THAT MATTER.
YOU KNOW, IF I HAD BEEN ASKED, I
WOULD HAVE SUPPORTED IT.
I SUPPORT THE BRADY BAN.
I WAS QUITE ACTIVE WITH MAYORS
ON THE GUN ISSUE AT THE TIME
THAT THE ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN WAS
EXPIRING.
AND WAS QUITE ACTIVE WITH MAYOR
BLOOMBERG ON OTHER ISSUES AROUND
GUNS.
I'VE BEEN TOLD SOMEONE SUBMITTED
THAT.
I'M NOT SURE THAT WAS AN
ACTIVELY DISCUSSED ITEM.
I DON'T BELIEVE SO.
WE GET A LOT OF LETTERS IN THE
OFFICE.
MOST OF THEM NEVER GET TO ME
QUITE FRANKLY.
SO I CAN'T TELL YOU THAT DIDN'T
HAPPEN.
I CAN ONLY TELL YOU THAT
SUPPORTS A PERSON'S OPPORTUNITY
TO HUNT.
AND TO MEET THE STRICTEST
DEFINITION OF THE SECOND
AMENDMENT, BUT BEYOND THAT I
THINK THIS THING HAS GOTTEN WAY
OUT OF CONTROL.
AND THE IDEA THAT ASSAULT
WEAPONS ARE AS PLENTIFUL IN THE
UNITED STATES WITH A CAPACITY AS
LARGE AS THEY'RE AVAILABLE IN
THE UNITED STATES, INCLUDING IN
CONNECTICUT, IS NOT SOMETHING I
SUPPORT.
I THINK THIS WHOLE ISSUE OF
ASSAULT WEAPONS AND WEAPONS THAT
CAN EASILY BE CONVERTED TO A
SALT WEAPONS IS A QUESTION WE
REALLY NEED TO HAVE IN THIS
COUNTRY.
OBVIOUSLY THE DISCUSSION CAN
BEGIN ABOUT THE SIZE OF THE
MAGAZINES, AND I THINK THAT'S A
GOOD DISCUSSION TO HAVE.
I'D LOVE TO HEAR THE PEOPLE
ARGUE THAT WE NEED 30-ROUND
MAGAZINES AND THAT'S SOMEHOW
TIED TO THE RIGHT TO BEAR ARMS.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
RIGHT, AND THEY SAY THAT BECAUSE
THEY KNOW THEY CAN PREVENT
ABOUT -- -- I'M NOT TALKING
ABOUT BASIC WEAPONS OR WEAPONS
USED IN HUNTING.
BEST OF MY KNOWLEDGE, IF ANYONE
USES AN ASSAULT WEAPON -- AN
ASSAULT WEAPON IN THE HUNTING
WITH THE 30-ROUND MAGAZINE, I'D
BE QUITE SURPRISED BY THAT --
AND BY THE WAY, IF THEY DO, AND
BECAUSE OF PUBLIC SAFETY, THAT
SHOULD GO AWAY, THEN I BELIEVE
THAT SHOULD GO AWAY.
>> PUBLIC POLICY DIDN'T SEE TO
BE PARTICULAR FOCUS OF YOURS
DURING THE FIRST HALF OF YOUR
TERM HERE -- WELL, I WAS
WONDERING IF YOU AGREE WITH THAT
OBSERVATION AND IF SO, WHY NOW?
>> I THINK GUN SAFETY IS -- HAS
BEEN IMPORTANT TO OUR
ADMINISTRATION AND THE FACT IS
WE ARE RANKED AS HAVING THE TOP
FIVE TOUGHEST LAWS ON GUNS IN
THE NATION.
BUT I WILL GO BACK TO WHAT I
SAID EARLIER.
ABSENT A FEDERAL FRAMEWORK --
DRILL DOWN FURTHER INTO MY OWN
PERSONAL HISTORY.
AS MAYOR OF STANFORD, WE CAME TO
UNDERSTAND THAT A BIG PERCENTAGE
OF THE HANDGUNS WORK THEIR WAY
UP FROM I-95 IN STATES IN WHICH
THERE ARE ACTUALLY EASIER GUN
LAWS AND GUNS IN SOME CASES SOLD
UNDER EXCEPTIONS TO THE RULE FOR
GUN SHOWS.
THOSE GUNS WORK THEIR WAY UP
I-95 AND GET TO PLACES LIKE NEW
YORK CITY OR CITIES IN OUR STATE
AND I'VE ALWAYS SAID THOSE
EXCEPTIONS IN THE ABSENCE OF A
TOUGHER FEDERAL LEGISLATION IS
NOT GOOD FOR CONNECTICUT, NOT
GOOD FOR OUR CITIES AND, AGAIN,
I ALSO HAVE FIRMLY BELIEVED THAT
THESE HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINES
ARE EXTREMELY DANGEROUS.
HAVING SAID THAT, BEING IN THE
TOP FIVE, I THINK THERE HAVE
BEEN PEOPLE WHO PREVIOUSLY
THOUGHT THEY'VE DONE ENOUGH IN
CONNECTICUT.
I'M NOT SAYING I'M ONE OF THOSE.
I DOUBT THERE IS ONE OF THOSE
LEFT.
>> -- DO YOU THINK IT MEETS THIS
STATE LAW, OUR STATE LAWS --
>> IT'S BEEN POINTED OUT, AND
I'VE TAKEN THE TIME TO POINT IT
OUT, THAT WE COULD BE COMPLIANT
WITH THE PREVIOUS ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN LIMITATION BY GOING
FROM A 30 MAGAZINE TO A 10
MAGAZINE.
I THINK THAT'S A COMMONSENSE
PIECE OF LEGISLATION THAT COULD
BE TAKEN UP.
>> -- ENOUGH INFORMATION TO SAY
MENTAL ILLNESS PLAYED A PART IN
THIS -- THIS SITUATION, AND HOW
WOULD YOU GO ABOUT IMPROVING
WHAT SEEMS TO BE A VERY
FRACTURED MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEM?
>> THE -- WITH RESPECT -- I
DON'T HAVE A DIAGNOSIS.
IT'S POSSIBLE THAT THE CRIMINAL
INVESTIGATION MAY HAVE TURNED
THAT UP.
I DON'T HAVE PERSONAL KNOWLEDGE
ABOUT IT.
MY COMMENTS ABOUT IT ARE IN
LARGE PART BASED ON THE NATURE
OF THE CRIME, HOW IT WAS CARRIED
OUT, THE FACT THAT HE KILLED HIS
MOTHER FIRST, THE FACT THAT HE
DROVE HIMSELF TO THE SCHOOL, HE
BROUGHT NUMEROUS WEAPONS WITH
HIM, AND A REPORTED HISTORY OF
ALIENATION AND BEHAVIORS THAT
WOULD BE CONSISTENT WITH THAT,
BUT DO I HAVE A DIAGNOSIS, THE
ANSWER'S NO.
>> HOW DO YOU THEN GO ABOUT
ADDRESSING IT ON A STATEWIDE
POLICY BASIS?
>> YOU KNOW, I THINK THAT MENTAL
ILLNESS HAS LONG BEEN DELEGATED
TO A DIFFERENT DISCUSSION THAN
PHYSICAL HEALTH, FOR INSTANCE.
IT IS A DISTINCTION THAT I THINK
IN MANY WAYS HAS NOT SERVED OUR
COUNTRY WELL.
I THINK THAT FIRST AND FOREMOST
WE NEED TO BEGIN IN EARNEST THE
PROCESS OF REMOVING THAT
DISCUSSION.
NOW, OVER THE LAST 20 YEARS,
THERE HAS BEEN SOME GRADUAL
CHANGE.
FOR INSTANCE, WITH RESPECT TO
COVERAGE UNDER INSURANCE PLANS
AND ACCESS TO SOME MENTAL HEALTH
SERVICES.
BUT WE HAVEN'T GONE FAR ENOUGH
THERE AS WELL.
I THINK WE ALL SUFFER WITH THE
PRESUMPTION -- NOT ALL BUT I
THINK MANY IN THE COUNTRY SUFFER
WITH THE PRESUMPTION THAT A
MENTAL ILLNESS CANNOT BE
RECOVERED FROM.
OF COURSE, THAT ISN'T THE CASE.
THERE ARE, JUST AS THERE ARE
UNTREATABLE OR UNCURABLE
PHYSICAL DISEASES, THERE ARE
CASES WHERE PEOPLE DO NOT
RECOVER FROM MENTAL ILLNESS, BUT
THERE ARE FAR MORE PHYSICAL
MALADIES THAT PEOPLE RECOVER
FROM AND THERE ARE FAR MORE
PSYCHOLOGICAL OR MENTAL ILLNESS
MALADIES THAT PEOPLE RECOVER
FROM.
THERE REALLY IS NO BASIS TO
SPEAK ABOUT AND TREAT THESE
THINGS DIFFERENTLY AND WE NEED
TO MOVE WELL BEYOND THAT.
>> -- BY CLOSING SO MANY MENTAL
HEALTH FACILITIES IN THE STATE
THAT COULD CONTRIBUTE TO SOME --
>> NO, I DON'T THING THAT'S THE
ISSUE.
I DON'T THING THAT'S THE ISSUE
AT ALL, TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH.
IN FACT, I WANT TO SAY JUST THE
OPPOSITE.
I'M A BIG BELIEVER THAT A GROUP
HOME OR ALTERNATIVE PLACEMENT IS
A FAR BETTER WAY TO ASSURE
POSITIVE OUTCOMES IN TREATING
MENTAL ILLNESS, DRUG ADDICTION,
AND OTHER MALADIES THAN TRYING
TO CONFINE PEOPLE TO LARGE
INSTITUTIONS WHERE THEY WERE
GENERALLY -- ACTUALLY, NOT
GENERALLY, WHERE THEY WERE
HISTORICALLY UNDERSERVED IN OUR
COUNTRY.
>> -- BUDGET DEFICIT DEAL
APPARENTLY IN THE WORKS --
>> I THINK THERE WERE
DISCUSSIONS LAST WEEK AND
DISCUSSIONS CONTINUED ON FRIDAY.
THERE ARE I THINK TENTATIVE
UNDERSTANDINGS WITH THE CAUCUS
LEADERS, THE FOUR CAUCUS
LEADERS, BUT THAT'S TENTATIVE.
THEY'VE NOT SHARED IT WITH THEIR
MEMBERS TO THE BEST OF MY
KNOWLEDGE.
IT'S CAPABLE OF BEING ADJUSTED
FURTHER.
BUT I THINK WE'RE ON A ROAD TO
HAVING AN AGREEMENT.
WHETHER, YOU KNOW, WHERE EXACTLY
THAT IS, I'VE GOT TO TELL YOU,
I'VE BEEN BUSY WITH A COUPLE
OTHER THINGS.
SO BEN BARNES CONTINUES TO HAVE
MEETINGS WITH LEADERS.
HE'LL CONTINUE TO DO THAT.
I'D LIKE TO DO IT ON A
BIPARTISAN BASIS.
I THINK WE SHOULD DO IT ON A
[ INAUDIBLE ]
I'LL GET YOU NEXT.
OKAY.
GO AHEAD.
[ INAUDIBLE ]
>> -- ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN COULD
BE RENEWED --
>> NO, LET ME JUST BE VERY
CLEAR.
THAT'S BEEN MY POSITION SINCE
WELL BEFORE THE BAN --
>> YES, YES, I KNOW THAT.
>> OKAY.
>> WHAT ABOUT SOME SORT OF
FEDERAL RULES OR REGULATIONS
REGARDING VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES
WHICH IT'S BEEN REPORTED THIS
YOUNG MAN WAS EITHER ADDICTED TO
OR WAS VERY ENTHUSIASTIC ABOUT.
WHERE YOU ACTUALLY DO SHOOT
PEOPLE IN THIS SIMULATED MANNER.
>> LET ME ASSURE YOU, I'VE NEVER
PLAYED ONE.
I THINK PARENTS HAVE TO THINK
ABOUT THOSE GAMES.
AND WHETHER ANYONE SHOULD BE
EXPOSED TO THEM OR AT WHAT AGE
THEY SHOULD BE EXPOSED TO THEM.
UNTIL I KNOW MORE ABOUT -- I'VE
READ SOME OF THE STUFF YOU'RE
COMMENTING ABOUT, ABOUT THIS
ASSAILANT.
WE'LL KNOW MORE, BUT DO I THINK
ENCOURAGING VIOLENCE TO BE
PLAYED OUT IN SUCH A REALISTIC
FASHION IS GOOD FOR PEOPLE, THE
ANSWER IS NO, I DON'T --
>> -- ON THE INVESTIGATION --
>> I GET BRIEFED ON IT BUT I'M
NOT -- I CERTAINLY DON'T WANT TO
SAY THINGS THAT WOULD IN ANY WAY
INPETE OUR OPERATING THEORIES
ABSENT SOMEONE DECIDING THAT
OPERATING THEORY IS IN FACT NOW
A CONCLUSION.
SO I'M AWARE OF THEORIES.
I'M AWARE OF PHYSICAL EVIDENCE
AND HOW IT'S BEING INTERPRETED.
BUT I CHOOSE TO AWAIT FINAL
INTERPRETATION OF THAT BY THE
FOLKS WHO HAVE DONE THIS ON A
MORE REGULAR BASIS THAN I HAVE.
YEAH, RIGHT HERE.
>> ON FRIDAY, YOU FOUND YOURSELF
IN AN UNIMAGINABLE POSITION OF
INFORMING THESE PEOPLE ABOUT THE
DEATH OF THEIR FAMILY MEMBERS.
IS THAT SOMETHING YOU -- VICTIM
OF CIRCUMSTANCE, DID YOU TELL
THE STATE POLICE, I'LL DO THAT?
CAN YOU GIVE US SOME DETAIL ON
THAT --
>> YEAH, I WAS -- IT WAS EVIDENT
TO ME THAT THERE WAS A
RELUCTANCE TO TELL PARENTS AND
LOVED ONES THAT THE PERSON THEY
WERE WAITING FOR WAS NOT GOING
TO RETURN.
AND THAT HAD GONE ON FOR A
PERIOD OF TIME.
WELL AFTER THERE WAS ANY
EXPECTANCY THAT FAMILIES WOULD
BE REUNITED.
SO I MADE A DECISION THAT RATHER
THAN RELYING ON TRADITIONAL
INVESTIGATIVE POLICIES, THAT YOU
ACTUALLY HAVE A CHILD OR AN
ADULT IDENTIFIED AS THE
PARTICULAR VICTIM, BEFORE YOU
INFORM SOMEONE, OR AT LEAST GIVE
THEM THE INFORMATION BY WHICH
THEY COULD FORMULATE FOR
THEMSELVES THAT THEIR LOVED ONE
WAS NOT GOING TO RETURN, I MADE
THE DECISION THAT TO HAVE THAT
GO ON ANY LONGER WAS WRONG.
I DID --
[ INAUDIBLE ]
I'M GOING TO ATTEND WHATEVER
NUMBER I CAN ATTEND.
TODAY WE HAD A CONFLICT.
FOR INSTANCE, TWO FUNERALS AT
THE SAME TIME.
ALTHOUGH NANCY WAS ABLE TO GET
DOWN TO NOAH'S WAKE BEFOREHAND,
SHE THEN WENT UP TO JACK'S
FUNERAL, AND I STAYED AT THE
FUNERAL IN FAIRFIELD.
SO I DON'T THINK I'M GOING TO
GET TO ALL OF THEM.
BUT I WOULD BE -- I THINK ONE OF
US -- ONE OF US WILL DO OUR
UTMOST TO ATTEND ANY FUNERAL
THAT WE'RE WELCOME AT.
OKAY.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> THANK YOU, GOVERNOR.
>> VISIBLY MOVED, THE GOVERNOR
OF THIS STATE OF CONNECTICUT,
DAN MALLOY, BRIEFING REPORTERS
ON WHAT IS GOING ON.
HE, LIKE THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES ON FRIDAY, CHOKED
BACK TEARS.
THIS IS A VERY SAD DAY, OF RAW
EMOTION HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AS FAMILIES BEGIN
BURYING THE CHILDREN KILLED IN
THE MASSACRE AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL RIGHT DOWN THE
ROAD FROM WHERE WE ARE RIGHT
NOW.
WE'RE WATCHING ALL OF THIS
UNFOLD, AND THE PAIN IS CLEARLY,
CLEARLY EVIDENT.
WHILE EVERY DAY HERE IN NEW TOWN
IS SAD, TODAY, IT'S ESPECIALLY,
IT'S ESPECIALLY SAD.
THIS AFTERNOON, THE FIRST
FUNERALS WERE HELD FOR VICTIMS
OF THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
MASSACRE.
CONNECTICUT'S GOVERNOR, YOU JUST
SAW HIM HERE, HE ATTENDED ONE OF
THE SERVICES TODAY, AND HE
SUMMED IT UP THIS WAY, AND I'M
QUOTING HIM, YOU SEE LITTLE
COFFINS AND YOUR HEART STARTS TO
ACHE.
AS THIS TOWN AND THE NATION
TRIES TO COME TO GRIPS WITH THIS
HUGE, HUGE TRAGEDY, THE
INVESTIGATION IS FOCUSING IN ON
THE QUESTION WHY.
SOME OF THE ANSWERS MAY COME
FROM A COMPUTER FOUND IN THE
HOME WHERE THE GUNMAN, ADAM
LANZA, LIVED WITH HIS MOTHER.
CNN'S NATIONAL CORRESPONDENT
DEBORAH FEYERICK IS KEEPING
TRACK OF THE LATEST
DEVELOPMENTS.
SHE'S JOINING US NOW LIVE WITH
MORE.
WHAT ARE YOU LEARNING, DEB?
>> WOLF, WE CAN TELL YOU LAW
ENFORCEMENT SOURCES ARE TELLING
US THE COMPUTER IS BEING
ANALYZED.
IT WAS FOUND SMASHED INSIDE THE
HOME, AND INVESTIGATORS RIGHT
NOW GATHERED UP THE PIECE,
PUTTING IT TOGETHER, TRYING TO
CHECK ALL THE FORENSICS ON IT,
WHO HE MAY HAVE BEEN IN CONTACT
WITH, E-MAILS, WEBSITES.
ANYTHING THAT MAY GIVE THEM SOME
INSIGHT INTO WHAT HE WAS
THINKING IN THE DAYS AND THE
MOMENTS LEADING UP TO THIS
CRIME.
WE WANT TO TELL YOU THAT AROUND
3:00, TWO UNMARKED POLICE CARS
TRAVELED UP THE LONG DRIVEWAY
AND YOU CAN SEE, THIS IS AS
CLOSE AS WE'VE GOTTEN TO THE
HOME SINCE THIS ALL HAPPENED.
THREE PEOPLE DID ENTER THAT
HOME.
WE BELIEVE THEY'RE
INVESTIGATORS.
I CAN ALSO TELL YOU, WOLF,
SOMETHING EQUALLY SAD.
ON OUR WAY HERE, WE NOTICED
THERE WERE MARKED SQUAD CARS IN
THE DRIVEWAYS OF SOME OF THE
NEARBY HOMES.
WE'VE BEEN TOLD BY CONNECTICUT
POLICE THAT ANY HOME DIRECTLY
AFFECTED BY THIS TRAGEDY WOULD
HAVE THOSE CARS IN THEIR
DRIVEWAYS.
SO WE'RE TRYING TO CONFIRM
WHETHER, IN FACT, THE HOMES
NEARBY THE LANZAS MAY HAVE BEEN
AFFECTED.
CNN CONFIRMED NANCY LANZA, THE
MOM, WHO WAS SHOT AND KILLED BY
HER OWN SON, SHOT IN THE HEAD,
BY HER OWN GUN, THAT, IN FACT,
SHE HAD CONFIDED TO FRIENDS THAT
THIS WAS THEIR LAST WINTER HERE,
THAT THEY WERE PLANNING ON
MOVING, THAT SHE THOUGHT ABOUT
POSSIBLY GOING TO WASHINGTON
STATE, POSSIBLY ENROLLING HER
SON IN A COLLEGE THERE.
WE'VE BEEN ABLE TO TRACE A
LITTLE BIT OF HIS ACADEMIC
HISTORY, WOLF.
WE CAN TELL YOU, RIGHT NOW,
THERE IS NO KNOWN CONNECTION TO
THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
HE FIRST APPEARS IN PUBLIC
RECORDS AS A FRESHMAN IN HIGH
SCHOOL BACK IN 2007, AND AT THAT
TIME, WE SPOKE TO A SECURITY
DIRECTOR, WHO SAID THAT ADAM
LANZA IMMEDIATELY WAS IDENTIFIED
AS A CHILD THAT NEEDED TO BE
WATCHED.
NOT BECAUSE HE WAS A THREAT TO
OTHER PEOPLE, THAT HE WAS SO
GAWKY AND SO AWKWARD THAT
SECURITY OFFICIALS FELT THAT
OTHERS MAY BE A THREAT TO HIM.
SO NOT ONLY DID THEY KEEP AN EYE
ON HIM, BUT ALSO HE WAS, AT THAT
TIME, ASSIGNED A SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST.
HE LEFT THAT SCHOOL IN ABOUT
2008.
HE ENROLLED IN CLASSES AT A
NEARBY UNIVERSITY, JUST ABOUT 15
MINUTES FROM HERE.
HE WAS TAKING COMPUTER SCIENCE,
MACRO ECONOMIC, AMERICAN
HISTORY.
THIS IS A 16-YEAR-OLD KID, MIND
YOU, HE WAS TAKING THOSE
CLASSES.
IN 2009, HE JUST FELL OFF THE
GRID, NEVER WENT BACK TO THE
SCHOOL.
HE TOOK UP SHOOTING AS A HOBBY.
THE ATF TELLING US HE WAS
SPOTTED AT A LOCAL GUN RANGE.
EVEN HIS MOM SAYING TO A FRIEND
THAT IT WAS A HOBBY, THAT HE
ENJOYED AND HE WANTED TO PURSUE.
WOLF.
>> DEBORAH FEYERICK, THANKS VERY
MUCH.
PEOPLE ACROSS THE NATION HAVE
BECOME FASCINATED BY THE STORIES
OF THE 20 CHILDREN, THE 6 WOMEN,
ALL EDUCATORS, WHO DIED AT THE
SCHOOL, AND THEY'RE REACHING OUT
TO NEWTOWN, SENDING GIFTS FOR
THE MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS THAT ARE
SPRINGING UP ALL OVER THIS TOWN.
CNN'S BROOK BALDWIN IS HERE.
SHE CAUGHT UP WITH A FIRST
RESPONDER DELIVERING CHRISTMAS
WREATHS FROM OREGON.
AS BROOK DISCOVERED, HAS QUITE A
STORY TO TELL US.
BROOK, THE STORY IS POWERFUL.
IT'S A SYMPTOM, A SYMBOL OF WHAT
HAS GOING ON HERE.
YOU AND I HAVE WALKED AROUND
THIS TOWN.
PEOPLE JUST WANT TO SHOW SOME
EMOTION.
>> IT'S PRETTY INCREDIBLE.
IT'S BEEN DIFFICULT TO TALK TO
SOME OF THE FIRST RESPONDERS.
YOU CAN SEE IT IN THEIR EYES
WHAT THEY SAW BUT THEY DON'T
EXACTLY WANT TO SHARE IT AND
WE'RE RESPECTING IT.
I HAPPENED UPON THE TOWN SQUARE
WHERE I SEE BOX AFTER BOX AND I
SAID, WHAT ARE YOU DELIVERING,
HANGING UP, AND IT WAS A WREATH,
26 WREATHS FROM A PERFECT
STRANGER, A WREATH FROM ACROSS
THE COUNTRY IN PORTLAND, OREGON.
HERE'S WHAT HE SHARED WITH ME.
HOW MANY WREATHS ARE THERE?
>> 26.
>> DID THEY GET SENT TO THE
FIREHOUSE?
>> SENT TO THE FIREHOUSE THROUGH
U.P.S.
>> DID YOU KNOW THEY WERE
COMING?
>> NO, NO, THEY WERE -- THE
TRUCK PULLED UP AND SHE SAYS, I
HAVE A DELIVERY.
WE UNLOADED THEM ALL AND WE
FIGURED WE'D COME UP WITH A
PLACE TO PUT THEM, TRY TO KEEP
THEM ALL TOGETHER.
GOT SHIPPED ALL THE WAY FROM
OREGON.
>> HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN HERE?
>> SINCE FRIDAY.
>> WHERE ARE YOU BASED OUT OF?
>> THE SANDY HOOK FIREHOUSE.
>> HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN AT THE
FIREHOUSE?
>> WE'RE GOING HOME AT NIGHT TO
SLEEP BUT --
>> YEARS?
>> SINCE HIGH SCHOOL.
I'M 38.
>> DID YOU EVER IN 1 MILLION
YEARS THINK YOU'D BE
EXPERIENCING THIS?
>> NOBODY IN THIS TOUB WOULD
THING THAT.
>> WHERE WERE YOU WHEN YOU
HEARD?
>> WORKING.
WORKING ACROSS TOWN.
WE SAW THE HELICOPTERS.
>> WHAT DID YOU THINK IT WAS?
>> WE THOUGHT IT WAS ONE OR TWO.
THE PRINCIPAL AT FIRST AND -- WE
CAME DOWN THE ROAD, IT WAS JUST
ALL SURREAL.
SEEING ALL THE CARS, ALL THIS.
IT'S TOUGH.
>> WHERE DID YOU GO ONCE YOU SAW
THE CARS, STRAIGHT TO THE
FIREHOUSE?
>> STRAIGHT TO THE FIREHOUSE.
FROM THERE, WE JUST --
>> HELP US AROUND THE WORLD
UNDERSTAND WHAT YOU, AS A FIRST
RESPONDER, ARE GOING THROUGH.
>> SADNESS, ANGER, GUILT IN SOME
ASPECTS.
>> WHY GUILT?
WHAT COULD YOU HAVE DONE?
>> EXACTLY.
WE WERE HAVING COUNSELING.
AS A GROUP.
>> JUST FINALLY WHAT DO YOU MAKE
OF THE WREATHS, JUST PEOPLE YOU
DON'T KNOW SENDING YOU ALL THESE
WREATHS TO PUT UP IN YOUR TOWN,
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY TO THE PEOPLE
OF PORTLAND, OREGON?
>> THANK YOU.
IT MAKES US FEEL WARM TO KNOW --
THIS IS AMAZING THAT PEOPLE THAT
FAR AWAY CARE ABOUT US.
>> IT WAS THE SAME FIREHOUSE IN
WHICH A LOT OF THOSE PARENTS
WERE WAITING FRIDAY MORNING TO
FIND OUT THE FATES OF THEIR SONS
AND DAUGHTERS.
TO GET OUT AND HANG THESE 26
WREATHS IN THE MIDDLE OF THE
TOWN SQUARE AND JUST THOSE TWO
SIMPLE WORDS, "THANK YOU," YOU
CAN JUST TELL IT MEANT THE WORLD
TO THESE GUYS.
>> I JUST MYSELF WALKED UP TO
THAT FIREHOUSE AND I SAW THOSE
LITTLE TREES, SAW THE TOYS, THE
FLOWERS, EVERYTHING --
>> THE STUFFED ANIMALS --
>> I WALKED IN, I SPENT SOME
TIME, A LITTLE TIME WITH SOME OF
THE FIRST RESPONDERS THERE WHO
WERE -- WE'RE GOING TO SHOW IT
TO OUR VIEWERS LATER.
THEY ALL SAID THE SAME THING
THEY SAID TO YOU.
THEY NEVER EXPECTED THAT THEY
WOULD BE -- AND THAT'S SORT OF
THE COMMAND CENTER.
IT'S A CRIME SCENE BECAUSE THAT
FIREHOUSE IS RIGHT DOWN THE
STREET FROM THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
AND THAT'S WHERE THEY'RE REVIEW
EVERYTHING, THEY'RE CHECKING
EVERYTHING, AND I WAS GOING TO
MEET WITH ONE OF THE LEAD
COMMANDERS OVER THERE, BUT THEY
WERE BUSY RETURNING PERSONAL
EFFECTS OF SOME OF THOSE WHO
WERE KILLED TO THEIR PARENTS AND
JUST --
>> IT'S A TOUGH SCENE AT THE
FIREHOUSE.
>> VERY TOUGH.
>> THANKS, WOLF.
>> WE NEVER EXPECTED TO BE
COVERING SOMETHING LIKE THIS
EITHER.
>> I NEVER WANT TO COVER
SOMETHING LIKE THIS AGAIN.
>> NEITHER DO I.
STUDENTS AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WON'T BE
RETURNING TO THEIR SCHOOL.
STAND BY.
WE HAVE THE LATEST ON THE PLANS
FOR ALL THE SURVIVORS, THEY'RE
CHANGING SCHOOLS.
STAY WITH US.
I HAVE A COLD,
AND I TOOK NYQUIL,
BUT I'M STILL STUBBED UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus Liquid Gels
SPEEDS RELIEF
TO YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A DECONGESTANT
FOR YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
THANKS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
PRETTY SWEET, HUH?
CUTE.
BUT DON'T YOU HAVE ANY APPS
ON YOUR PHONE
THAT CAN MAKE YOUR LIFE
EASIER?
WHO DO YOU THINK I AM,
Quicken Loans?
AT Quicken Loans, WE'LL PROVIDE
YOU WITH MYQL MOBILE.
THIS AMAZINGLY USEFUL APP
ALLOWS YOU
TO TAKE PICTURES
OF YOUR MORTGAGE DOCUMENTS
USING AN iPhone
OR Android SMART PHONE...
SO YOU CAN EASILY
SEND THEM TO US.
ONE MORE WAY Quicken Loans
IS Engineered to Amaze.
OOH, LA-LA!
>>> AMONG THE VICTIMS, JAMES
MATTIOLI.
HE WANTED TO WEAR SHORTS, HE
LOVED TO SWIM AND HE WAS ALWAYS
HUNGRY FOR HIS DAD'S OMELETS AND
HIS MOM'S FRENCH TOAST.
MEETINGS ARE UNDER WAY TO
PREPARE FOR THE REOPENING OF
SCHOOLS HERE IN NEWTOWN.
OFFICIALS SAY THE STUDENTS OF
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL ARE
DISMISSED UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE.
YOU HAD A CHANCE, KATE, TO MEET
WITH SOME FOLKS HERE WHO ARE
PLANNING TO DEAL WITH THIS
ISSUE.
IT'S A SENSITIVE ISSUE.
WHERE ARE THESE KIDS GOING TO GO
TO SCHOOL?
>> IT'S A MASSIVE UNDERTAKING.
OBVIOUSLY AFTER THE HORROR OF
FRIDAY, NO ONE IS READY TO SEND
CHILDREN, STUDENTS, BACK INTO
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY BUT AT THE
SAME TIME SO MANY FOLKS ARE
LOOKING FOR A SENSE OF NORMALCY.
THAT'S WHAT I'M HEARING OVER AND
OTHER AGAIN.
GETTING THE CHILDREN BACK ON A
PATH TO HEALING.
THAT'S WHERE THE CITY MONROE
STEPPED IN.
TRUCK LOADS FILLED WITH
EVERYTHING FROM DESKS TO
BULLETIN BOARDS LEAVING SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY.
HEADING HERE TO THE NEIGHBORING
TOWN OF MONROE.
>> WHEN THE CHILDREN COME IN,
WHENEVER THE SCHOOL IS STARTED,
THEY WALK INTO A CLASSROOM THAT
IS AS CLOSE AS POSSIBLE TO THEIR
CLASSROOM THEY LEFT.
>> Reporter: THIS IS THE TOWN'S
CHIEF EXECUTIVE.
HE SAID AS SOON AS HE HEARD
ABOUT THE HORROR AT SANDY HOOK,
HE OFFERED UP CHALK HILL MIDDLE
SCHOOL.
IT'S EMPTY BECAUSE IT CLOSED
RECENTLY.
HE MET WITH SOME OF THE STUDENTS
AND TEACHER IT IS AT SUNDAY'S
VIGI
VIGIL.
>> MOST OF THEM WERE VERY
THANKFUL THEY HAD A CHANCE TO GO
BACK TO WORK.
THE CHILDREN AND THE TEACHERS
WERE -- IT WAS EMOTIONAL.
>> Reporter: ALL DAY,
CONTRACTORS DONATED THEIR TIME
TO TRANSFORM THIS FORMER MIDDLE
SCHOOL INTO AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
>> JUST TO GIVE YOU A SENSE.
THE TOILETS ALL HAVE TO BE
REPLACED.
TO A SMALLER SIZE.
YOU KNOW, THINGS HAVE TO BE MADE
ACCESSIBLE.
TOWEL DISPENSERS, THINGS LIKE
THAT, LOWERED.
>> Reporter: JIM IS MONROE'S
SUPERINTENDENT.
>> WHY IS IT SO IMPORTANT TO GET
THE STUDENTS OF SANDY HOOK INTO
A BUILDING LIKE CHALK HILL AND
BACK IN THEIR CLASSROOM?
>> WELL, THAT'S EXACTLY THE
SENSE OF NORMALCY THAT THEY NEED
TO BEGIN THE HEALING PROCESS.
AND TO FEEL SAFE AND PROTECTED.
AND TO GET BACK INTO A ROUTINE.
>> Reporter: ONE CHANGE EVERY
PARENT WILL NOTICE AT SCHOOLS
ACROSS THE AREA AFTER SANDY
HOOK, POLICE PATROL.
IS THAT A PROTECTIVE MEASURE?
IS THAT THE NEW NORMAL?
OR IS THAT MORE A WAY TO HELP
FAMILIES AND STUDENTS ALLEVIATE
SOME ANXIETY AS THEY RETURN TO
CLASS?
>> ALL OF THE ABOVE.
ALL OF THE ABOVE.
UNFORTUNATELY, IT MAY BE THE NEW
NORMAL.
IT MAY BE THE WAY WE HAVE TO
TAKE COURSE, TAKE ACTION IN THE
FUTURE.
>> Reporter: NOW, THERE'S NO
OFFICIAL START DATE FOR THE
STUDENTS TO BEGIN BACK -- WELL,
TORE BEGIN IN THEIR NEW SCHOOL
AT CHALK HILL MIDDLE SCHOOL, IN
THAT BUILDING, BUT OFFICIALS IN
THAT TOWN SAY THE BUILDING AT
LEAST COULD BE READY AS EARLY AS
TOMORROW, WHICH IS AN AMAZING
THING TO THINK ABOUT.
THEY'RE REALLY COMPLETELY
TRANSFORMING THIS BUILDING IN
JUST A MATTER OF DAYS.
BUT WHEN THEY WANT TO BRING THE
STUDENTS BACK INTO SCHOOL,
THAT'S COMPLETELY UP TO THE
NEWTOWN SCHOOL OFFICIALS.
THERE'S NO WORD YET IF THEY WANT
TO START BACK.
>> THERE WERE ALMOST 600 KIDS IN
THAT KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HERE
THAT'S OBVIOUSLY NOW A CRIME
SCENE.
>> THAT'S NOW A CRIME SCENE BUT
IT'S AMAZING HOW THEY'RE DOING
EVERYTHING THEY CAN.
YOU CAN SEE IN THOSE TRUCK LOADS
OF THINGS.
THEY'RE TRYING TO REPLICATE
ALMOST DOWN TO THE DESK AND THE
CHAIR AND THE PICTURE ON THE
WALL, EACH ROOM, AS MUCH AS THEY
CAN, IN ORDER TO TRY TO GIVE
THEM A SENSE OF NORMALCY, OF
SAFETY, OF SOMETHING THAT
THEY'RE FAMILIAR WITH, TO TRY TO
GET THEM ON THE PATH TO HEALING.
BUT THIS FRIDAY IS SUPPOSED TO
BE THE LAST DAY BEFORE HOLIDAY
BREAK FOR MANY, FOR I THINK
EVERY SCHOOL IN THE AREA, SO
IT'S UP TO -- IF THEY WANT TO
GET THEM BACK FOR A COUPLE DAYS
OR AFTER THE HOLIDAY.
>> THEY GOT TO GET INTO A
ROUTINE TOO.
I GUESS IT'S GOOD THEY'RE GOING
TO HAVE THE CHRISTMAS BREAK
COMING UP SO THEY WON'T -- THAT
WILL BE NORMAL FOR THEM TO JUST
SPEND SOME TIME WITH THEIR
FAMILIES.
>> WITH THEIR FAMILY.
WHICH WE KNOW IS IMPORTANT.
>> KATE WILL BE WITH US
THROUGHOUT OUR COVERAGE HERE.
CAN AMERICA PREVENT TRAGEDIES
LIKE NEWTOWN FROM HAPPENING
AGAIN?
WHAT NEEDS TO CHANGE?
WE'LL TAKE A CLOSER LOOK AT WHAT
PARENTS AND COMMUNITIES CAN DO.
>>> RIGHT HERE IN NEW TOWN, ALL
THESE MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS ARE
SPRINGING UP.
CNN'S DON LEMON IS RIGHT IN THE
MIDDLE OF ALL OF THIS.
DON, WALK US THROUGH, EXPLAIN TO
OUR VIEWERS WHAT YOU'RE SEEING
AND WHAT'S GOING ON, BECAUSE
THIS IS SUCH A POWERFUL AND
EMOTIONAL PART OF THIS STORY.
>> POWERFUL IS RIGHT,
HEARTWARMING, RIGHT.
WOLF, FLOWERS HERE, TEDDY BEARS,
CANDLES, SEEMS TO BE THE THEME
HERE.
AS YOU AND I WERE TALKING
YESTERDAY, WHEN I ARRIVED HERE
ON SATURDAY, IT WAS JUST CANDLES
HERE.
JUST A SMALL NUMBER OF CANDLES.
AND NOW THIS HAS GROWN.
THIS APPEARS TO HAVE BECOME THE
HEART OF THIS NEWTOWN COMMUNITY,
PEOPLE GATHERING HERE ALL DAY
AND ALL NIGHT FOR 24 HOURS, 24
HOURS A DAY THEY'VE BEEN DOING
THIS.
WANT TO WALK OVER HERE AND SHOW
YOU SOME OF THE THINGS THEY'RE
PUTTING UP.
YOU SEE THIS ORAGAMI HERE, SOME
PEOPLE CALL THEM JAPANESE BIRDS
THEY PUT UP FOR BLESSINGS FOR
EVERYONE INVOLVED.
I WANT TO TALK WITH EMILY AND
PAULINA AND LAUREN.
YOU GUYS HAVE BEEN OUT HERE.
I SAW YOU HUGGING AND CRYING.
YOU'VE BEEN HERE FOR A WHILE.
>> WE'VE BEEN HERE FOR ABOUT I
DON'T KNOW MAYBE HALF AN HOUR
NOW.
>> WHY DID YOU WANT TO COME OUT?
>> LIVED IN NEWTOWN MY WHOLE
LIFE.
I USED TO GO TO SANDY HOOK TILL
I WAS 7.
YOU COULD WALK ANYWHERE, FEEL
OKAY.
SUCH A GREAT COMMUNITY.
WE'RE JUST -- I'M JUST PROUD OF
THIS TOWN, I REALLY AM.
ALL THE SUPPORT EVERYONE'S
GIVING US, I WANT EVERYONE TO
KNOW HOW IMPORTANT IT IS, WE
REALLY APPRECIATE IT.
>> YOU'VE BEEN VERY EMOTIONAL AS
WELL.
>> SAME THING, I'VE LIVED HERE
MY ENTIRE LIFE.
MY KARATE SCHOOL'S RIGHT AROUND
THE CORNER.
IT'S MY SECOND HOME.
I LOOK ON TV LIKE ALL THIS STUFF
AND I -- IT'S NOT MY HOME
ANYMORE, LIKE, IT'S NOT THE
SAME.
>> WOLF, PEOPLE ARE SAYING THEY
DON'T WANT TO -- THANK YOU,
LADIES, THANK YOU.
WE'RE THINKING ABOUT YOU.
THEY DON'T WANT THIS TO BE WHAT
THEIR TOWN IS REMEMBERED FOR.
BUT, AGAIN, IF YOU LOOK AT THIS,
IT'S EVEN GOING FURTHER DOWN THE
STREET.
AT FIRST, IT WAS JUST IN THE
MIDDLE OF THE SQUARE WHERE THEY
HAVE THE CHRISTMAS TREE AND NOW
IT IS -- THERE ARE TEDDY BEARS
UPON TEDDY BEARS, FLOWERS UPON
FLOWERS, AND LAYERS UPON LAYERS
OF THINGS THAT PEOPLE ARE
DROPPING OFF AND NOTES SAYING
"PRAY FOR THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN,
DON'T GIVE UP HOPE," AND YOU CAN
SEE IT HERE.
THIS IS WHERE PEEP COME OUT AND
THEY POUR THEIR LOVE AND THEIR
WORDS.
WE'VE EVEN SEEN PEOPLE PRAYING
OPENLY OUT HERE AND EMBRACING
AND PEOPLE DROPPING OFF FLOWERS
ALL DAY.
NOT JUST SINGLE FLOWERS, WOLF.
THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO ARE --
EXPENSIVE ARRANGEMENTS THEY'VE
BROUGHT HERE, POINSETTIAS,
BALLOONS.
REALLY JUST COMING OUT TO SHARE
THAT THEY'RE THINKING AND WHAT
THEY'RE FEELING.
AS WE HAVE BEEN SEEING THE WHO
TIME, TO A PERSON, THEY SAY, I
DON'T WANT TO FEEL HELPLESS.
I WANT TO COME OUT AND I WANT TO
SUPPORT MY COMMUNITY.
>> ONE OF THE SADDEST THINGS IS
TO SEE THE NOTES THAT LITTLE
CHILDREN LEAVE FOR THE 20 YOUNG
KIDS, 6-YEAR-OLDS AND
7-YEAR-OLDS WHO WERE KILLED
FRIDAY MORNING HERE AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
YOU REALLY CAN'T GO MUCH
ANYWHERE IN THIS TOWN RIGHT NOW
WITHOUT SEEING THESE LITTLE
MEMORIALS SPRINGING UP.
PEOPLE ARE DRIVING FROM ALL OVER
THE STATE, FROM ALL OVER THE
COUNTRY, WITH LITTLE GIFTS,
LITTLE MEMENTOS, BECAUSE THEY
WANT TO BE PART OF THIS, THEY
WANT TO REMEMBER WHAT HAPPENED.
HOPEFULLY, WE WAON'T SEE THIS
AGAIN.
DON, WE'LL COME BACK TON YOU
SOON.
PRESIDENT OBAMA CALLS FOR A
UNITED EFFORT TO STOP THE
VIOLENCE.
WE'LL TALK WITH CNN'S DR. DREW
PINSKY ABOUT WHAT IT MIGHT TAKE.
STAY WITH US.
[ Male Announcer ] HOW CAN
POWER CONSUMPTION IN CHINA,
IMPACT WOOL EXPORTS
FROM NEW ZEALAND,
TEXTILE PRODUCTION IN SPAIN,
AND THE USE OF MEDICAL
TECHNOLOGY IN THE U.S.?
AT T. ROWE PRICE,
WE UNDERSTAND THE CONNECTIONS
OF A COMPLEX, GLOBAL ECONOMY.
IT'S JUST ONE REASON
OVER 75% OF OUR MUTUAL FUNDS
BEAT THEIR 10-YEAR
LIPPER AVERAGE.
T. ROWE PRICE.
INVEST WITH CONFIDENCE.
REQUEST A PROSPECTUS
OR SUMMARY PROSPECTUS
WITH INVESTMENT INFORMATION,
RISKS, FEES AND EXPENSES
TO READ AND CONSIDER CAREFULLY
BEFORE INVESTING.
PLAYS A KEY ROLE
THROUGHOUT OUR LIVES.
One A Day Women's 50+
IS A COMPLETE MULTIVITAMIN
DESIGNED FOR WOMEN'S HEALTH
CONCERNS AS WE AGE.
IT HAS 7 ANTIOXIDANTS
TO SUPPORT CELL HEALTH.
One A Day 50+.
>>> CHASE KOWALSKI COMPLETED HIS
FIRST LITTLE KID'S MINI
TRIATHLON.
HE WAS A CUB SCOUT WHO PLAYED
BASEBALL, ENJOYED THE KIDS
WORKSHOP AT THE HOME DEPOT AS
WELL, 7 YEARS OLD.
INJO
INJOINING US NOW, DR. DREW
PINSKE.
THANKS SO MUCH.
HOW IMPORTANT IS IT FIRST OF ALL
FOR THESE OTHER KIDS, NEARLY 600
OF THEM, TO GET BACK INTO A
REGULAR SCHOOL ROUTINE?
>> IT'S VERY IMPORTANT, WOLF,
THAT THESE PARENTS TELL THEIR
KIDS THAT THEY'RE GOING TO BE
SAFE AND THEY NEED TO GET BACK
TO THEIR LIVES.
IMPORTANT TO GIVE SORROW AND
TRAUMA WORDS, ALLOW THE KIDS TO
TALK ABOUT THESE THINGS AND MAKE
SENSE OF THEM.
IT'S VERY IMPORTANT FOR ALL OF
US, THE HEAD OF EVERY HOUSEHOLD,
THE HEAD OF EITHER COMMUNITY, TO
BEGIN TALKING ABOUT HEALING,
RETURNING TO A NORMAL LIFE, AND
AN UNDERSTANDING THAT ALTHOUGH
WE WILL NOT FORGET THIS, WE'RE
GOING TO BE OKAY, WE ARE
RESILIENT AND WE'RE NOT GOING TO
LET THIS HAPPEN TO OUR KIDS
AGAIN.
>> I KNOW YOU HEARD THE
PRESIDENT LAST NIGHT.
YOU'VE HEARD A LOT OF OTHER
POLITICIANS SPEAKING OUT RIGHT
NOW.
YOU'VE GOT SOME STRONG VIEWS.
WHAT DO WE NEED TO DO NOW AS A
COUNTRY TO TRY TO PREVENT THESE
KIND TRAGEDIES?
>> WE'RE LOOKING FOR LEADERSHIP.
ONE THING WE DO IN THE
PSYCHIATRIC HOSPITAL WHEN WE'RE
DEALING WITH VERY DISTURBED
PEOPLE IS WE FORM A TEAM THAT IS
A HEALTHY FAMILY.
WE MODEL A HEALTHY FAMILY.
AND WE HAVE A UNIFIED FRONT SO
THERE'S NO SPLITTING OF THAT
FRONT.
AND I CALL UPON OUR LEADERS AT
COMMUNITY, AT STATE, AND AT
FEDERAL LEVEL, TO MODEL A
HEALTHY FAMILY.
DIVISIVENESS AND SPLITTING IS
WHAT CAUSES THE MOST VULNERABLE
AMONGST US TO FEEL LIKE ACTING
OUT.
IT CREATES A VULNERABILITY TO
THESE KINDS OF THINGS.
TWO OTHER THINGS I WOULD SAY.
ONE IS PHYSICIANS MUST BE ABLE
TO DO THEIR JOB.
IF THEY HAVE AN INSTINK
SOMEBODY'S IN TROUBLE, THEY MUST
BE ABLE TO ACT ON THAT INSTINCT
DESPITE THE CONCERN FOR
SOMEBODY'S RIGHT, THE INSTINCT
IS TO PROTECT THE INDIVIDUAL AND
THE COMMUNITY FOR THEIR OWN
GOOD.
DOCTORS MUST BE ABLE TO DO THEIR
JOB.
NUMBER TWO, BECAUSE WE HAVE SUCH
WOU
WOEFUL MENTAL HEALTH SERVICES,
LAW ENFORCEMENT HAS BECOME THE
MENTAL HEALTH SERVICES OF LAST
RESORT.
WE MUST CALL UPON THEM.
I'M NOT ASKING WE FLOOD THE LAW
ENFORCEMENT SYSTEM.
BUT I CANNOT TELL YOU, WOLF, HOW
OFTEN I'M TELLING PARENTS AND
FAMILY MEMBERS TO JUST CALL LAW
ENFORCEMENT BECAUSE IT'S ALL WE
GOT AND YOU HAVE TO BE WILLING
TO DO THAT OR SOMETHING HORRIBLE
LIKE THIS WILL HAPPEN AGAIN.
>> BECAUSE WE REALLY DO KEEP
MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES AT A
DIFFERENT LEVEL THAN PHYSICAL
AILMENTS OUT THERE --
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> IT'S PART OF THE PROBLEM
HERE, ISN'T IT?
WE'VE GOT TO DO A LOT MORE --
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> -- TO EDUCATE PEOPLE ABOUT
MENTAL HEALTH.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
WE HAVE TO BE ABLE TO IDENTIFY
THE PROBLEMS AND THEN DOCTORS --
I WAS TALKING TO DR. OZ THIS
MORNING, SAYING, LOOK, YOU, IN
THE MIDDLE OF AN OPERATION, IF
SOMETHING GOES WRONG, COULD
IMPROVISE AND USE YOUR JUDGMENT.
IN MENTAL HEALTH, WE CAN'T DO
THAT.
ALL KINDS OF THINGS GET IN THE
WAY OF PHYSICIANS DOING THEIR
JOB.
BY THE SAME TOKEN, BECAUSE WE'RE
SO UNDERSERVED IN MENTAL HEALTH,
WE GOT NOTHING MUCH ELSE AT OUR
DISPOSAL BUT LAW ENFORCEMENT.
OF COURSE FAMILY AND FRIENDS AND
COMMUNITIES DON'T LIKE TO DO
THAT, BUT THEY'RE THERE TO HELP.
PHYSICIANS ARE THERE TO HELP.
LAW ENFORCEMENT IS THERE TO
HELP.
BUT BEYOND THAT, I REALLY
STRONGLY CALL UPON OUR LEADERS
TO, A, LET OUR CHILDREN KNOW
TODAY THAT THEY'RE GOING TO BE
FINE, AND, B, WE'RE GOING TO BE
A HEALTHY FAMILY, THAT WE ARE
COMMITTED TO AND WE'RE NOT GOING
TO SEE ALL THESE DIVISIVENESS
AND ENVY AND HATRED WHICH IS
REALLY -- ALONGSIDE OF ME WE'RE
LOOKING AT LOVE AND GRACE WHICH
IS THE RESPONSE TO THE ENVY AND
HATRED THAT RESULTED IN THE EVIL
THAT HAS HAPPENED IN THAT POOR
TOWN.
>> WHERE DO YOU COME DOWN,
DR. DREW, ON THE ISSUE OF
VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES, VIOLENT
FILMS AND LITTLE BOYS?
>> WELL, I MUST TELL YOU, WOLF,
I'VE GOT VERY STRONG FEELINGS
ABOUT THIS.
TWOFOLD.
ONE IS WE KNOW THAT IT'S NOT A
GOOD THING.
THERE'S NO DOUBT ABOUT IT NOT
BEING GOOD FOR KIDS.
PARTICULARLY VULNERABLE KIDS.
REMEMBER, HERE, WE HAVE A YOUNG
MAN WHO WENT OUT AND WAS
SHOOTING GUNS SO THERE -- HE'S
GONE TO THE NEXT LEVEL WITH
THE -- YOU KNOW, FROM A TOY GUN
OR A VIDEO GAME TO SHOOTING
GUNS.
BUT OF GRAVER CONCERN, THIS HAS
NOT BEEN STUDIED YET, IS THAT
PEOPLE TODAY FEEL ENTITLED TO
ACT OUT ON REAL PEOPLE IN SOCIAL
MEDIA.
THE KIND OF VENOM AND HATRED
THAT IS EXPRESSED TOWARDS ACTUAL
PEOPLE WHO RECEIVE IT AND READ
IT AND THE ENTITLEMENT YOUNG
PEOPLE HAVE TO ACT THAT OUT IN
SOCIAL MEDIA, I THINK THAT IS
WHERE THE DISASSOCIATION COMES
AND THE DISCONNECT THAT ALLOWS
PEOPLE TO LOSE EMPATHY THAT CAN
RESULT IN SOMETHING HORRIBLE
LIKE THIS.
>> WHY IS IT ALWAYS -- IT SEEMS
TO BE ALMOST ALWAYS YOUNG MEN OR
BOYS WHO ARE INVOLVED IN THESE
KINDS OF MASS MURDERS AS OPPOSED
TO GIRLS OR YOUNG WOMEN.
>> YEAH.
WELL, THE REASON IS THAT'S MEN,
NUMBER ONE, I MEAN, THAT IS
SIMPLY THE FACT, MEN ARE MORE
LIKELY TO ACT OUT VIOLENTLY.
18 TO 25 IS THE WINDOW WHEN
MAJOR MENTAL ILLNESS EMERGES.
THINGS LIKE SCHIZOPHRENIA,
BIPOLAR MANIA, MORE SERIOUS
MANIFESTATIONS OF PERSONALITY
DISORDERS AND AGGRESSION.
THAT'S THE WINDOW WHEN THIS
COMES ON.
THOSE KIDS WHO HAVE INTERVENTION
DURING THAT WINDOW ARE LESS
LIKELY TO HAVE THE CHRONIC
LONG-TERM PROBLEMS.
BUT IF YOU DON'T INTERVENE THEN,
YOU'RE LIKELY TO HAVE SOMEONE
WHO PROGRESSES AND WORSENS AND
WHO HAS A LIFETIME OF PROBLEMS.
>> LOTS OF STUDY.
WE NEED ACTION SOON.
OTHERWISE THESE --
>> NONE OF US -- WE ALL HAVE GOT
TO BE A PART OF THE SOLUTION
TODAY, TODAY, TODAY, WE'VE GOT
TO START TODAY, NOW, THAT'S IT.
>> DR. DREW, THANKS VERY MUCH.
THIS IMPORTANT NOTE TO OUR
VIEWERS, YOU CAN SEE "DR. DREW
ON CALL" WEEKNIGHTS AT 9:00 P.M.
EASTERN ON OUR SISTER NETWORK
HLN.
>>> REMEMBERING SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AS A PLACE OF
LOVE AND NOW LOSS.
A LONGTIME MEMBER OF THAT
COMMUNITY SHARES HER MEMORIES.
WELCOME TO CHEVY'S
YEAR-END EVENT.
SO, THE 5.3-LITER V8 SILVERADO
CAN TOW UP TO 9,600 POUNDS?
315 HORSEPOWER.
WHAT'S THAT IN
REINDEER-POWER?
[ laughs ]
[ pencil scratches ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHEVY'S GIVING MORE.
GET THE BEST OFFER
OF THE YEAR --
0% APR FINANCING FOR 60 MONTHS
PLUS $1,000 HOLIDAY BONUS CASH.
PLUS TRADE UP FOR AN ADDITIONAL
$1,000 TRADE-IN ALLOWANCE.
HURRY.
BONUS CASH ENDS JANUARY 2ND.
but with ADVAIR,
I'm breathing better.
So now I can be in
the scene.
ADVAIR is
clinically proven to help
significantly improve
lung function.
Unlike most COPD medications,
ADVAIR contains both an
anti-inflammatory
and a
long-acting bronchodilator
working together to help improve
your lung function all day.
ADVAIR won't
replace fast-acting inhalers
for sudden symptoms
and should not be used more
than twice a day.
People with
COPD taking ADVAIR
may have a higher chance
of pneumonia.
ADVAIR may increase your
risk of osteoporosis
and some eye problems.
Tell your doctor
if you have a heart condition
or high blood pressure before
taking ADVAIR.
If you're still
having difficulty breathing,
ask your doctor if including
ADVAIR could help
improve your lung function.
Get your
first full
prescription
free
and save
on refills
at
ADVAIRcopd.com.
>>> THIS AFTERNOON, THE FIRST OF
SO MANY FUNERALS TO COME FOR THE
NEWTOWN VICTIMS.
6-YEAR-OLD NOAH POZNER AND JACK
PINTO WERE LAID TO REST TODAY.
JOINING US NOW IS THE FORMER
CHAIR OF THE BOARD OF EDUCATION.
THIS MUST BE SO DIFFICULT FOR
YOU.
YOU KNEW SOME OF THESE PEOPLE
WHO WERE KILLED.
SO WHAT WAS IT LIKE?
>> GOING THROUGH THIS EXPERIENCE
YOU MEAN?
OH, IT'S BEEN HORRIFIC.
FROM THE MOMENT WE ALL HEARD THE
NEWS, IT WAS DEVASTATING TO KNOW
THAT SOMEONE HAD COME INTO THE
SCHOOL WITH A GUN, THAT ALONE
WAS HORRIBLE ENOUGH BECAUSE IT'S
A PLACE OF PEACE AND JOY.
BUT NOW AS WE GO FORWARD AND
WE'VE LEARNED THE NAMES AND NOW
WE'RE GOING THROUGH THE GRUELING
PROCESS OF THE FUNERALS, IT'S
VERY, VERY, VERY HARD.
EVERYONE USES THE WORD "HOLLOW."
THAT'S WHERE WE'RE AT NOW.
>> I CERTAINLY WANT TO RESPECT
THE PRIVACY OF THE PARENTS AND
FAMILIES OF THE TWO LITTLE BOYS
WHO WERE BURIED TODAY.
YOU CAN'T IMAGINE -- YOU WERE
THERE, I DON'T KNOW IF YOU WANT
IT TO EVEN TELL US WHAT WAS
GOING ON.
>> I DON'T.
I DON'T WANT TO SAY WHICH ONE I
WENT TO EITHER.
>> YOU DON'T HAVE TO OBVIOUSLY.
>> BUT I WILL SAY THAT THE GRIEF
WAS OVERWHELMING IN THE PARKING
LOT AFTERWARDS FROM THOSE OF US
WHO HAVEN'T SEEN EACH OTHER YET
DURING THIS.
SO IT'S EVERYTHING YOU CAN
IMAGINE PLUS SOME.
IT'S WORSE.
>> HOW DO WE MOVE FORWARD?
HOW DOES THIS COMMUNITY MOVE
FORWARD?
BECAUSE THAT'S ONE OF YOUR
RESPONSIBILITIES.
>> YES.
I FEEL LIKE I SAID BEFORE THAT
WE REALLY NEED TO LEAD WITH
LOVE.
AND THAT'S WHAT I'M SEEING OUR
COMMUNITY DO.
WE'RE PUTTING OUR ARMS AROUND
PEOPLE.
BUT THERE'S ALSO THE
RESPONSIBILITY THAT AS WE START
THIS DISCUSSION ABOUT WHAT ARE
WE GOING TO DO NEXT AND I'M
SEEING SOME OF THIS ONLINE WHERE
PEOPLE ARE ALREADY STARTED TO
YELL AT EACH OTHER.
AND I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT IF
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE THESE
BROADER DISCUSSIONS ON ALL THE
ISSUES, NOT JUST GUN CONTROL,
MENTAL HEALTH, ALL THE OTHER
ISSUES, SCHOOL SAFETY, THEN WE
CAN'T YELL AT EACH OTHER.
THAT'S ALL WE'VE BEEN DOING IN
THIS COUNTRY, IT'S SO DIVISIVE.
>> HOW DO WE GET OVER THAT?
PEOPLE ARE SO PASSIONATE ON AN
ISSUE LIKE GUN CONTROL.
>> FIRST, WE'VE GOT TO LEARN HOW
TO HAVE DISCOURSE AND PUT THE
PASSION AWAY, AND I WOULD
SUGGEST THAT ONE OF THE WAYS WE
DO THAT, AS WE HAVE THESE
DISCUSSIONS, I WANT YOU TO MANG
YOU'RE TALKING TO ONE OF THESE
6-YEAR-OLDS.
IF THAT 6-YEAR-OLD WAS IN THE
ROOM WITH YOU, WOULD YOU SPEAK
LIKE THAT?
IMAGINE IF YOU'RE A POLITICAL
PERSON, IF THAT -- THOSE
TEACHERS HAD THE COURAGE TO DO
WHAT THEY DID, AND VICKY SOTO
HAD THE COURAGE, AND DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG, THEN LET'S HAVE OUR
POLITICIANS HAVE THE COURAGE TO
TALK CIVILLY TO EACH OTHER AND
FIGURE THESE ISSUES OUT.
WE CANNOT HAVE ANY MORE
6-YEAR-OLDS AND 7-YEAR-OLDS DIE
IN THEIR CLASSROOMS.
>> DO WE NEED GREATER SECURITY
AT ELEMENTARY, MIDDLE, HIGH
SCHOOLS HERE IN CONNECTICUT,
HERE IN THE UNITED STATES?
>> I THINK THAT'S A HUGE PART OF
THE DISCUSSION.
AND I DON'T KNOW IF IT'S
SECURITY OR PERHAPS IT'S OUR
BUILDING MATERIALS, THE GLASS
WAS EASILY, YOU KNOW, SHOT
THROUGH.
WHO WOULD HAVE EVER THOUGHT
THAT?
I DON'T KNOW --
>> BECAUSE HE FORCED HIS WAY
INTO THAT SCHOOL.
>> HE DID, FROM WHAT I
UNDERSTAND, HE SHOT THE WINDOWS
OUT.
YOU KNOW, WE HAD PREPARED FOR
EVERYTHING EXCEPT THAT.
I'M SURE MOST SCHOOLS IN THE
COUNTRY HAVEN'T CONSIDERED THAT
OPTION.
LIKE IN OKLAHOMA, THE BOMBING,
ONCE THAT HAPPENED, FEDERAL
BUILDINGS HAD BIG THINGS IN
FRONT OF THEM.
I DON'T WANT SCHOOLS TO BE A
FORTRESS, I REALLY DON'T, BUT
BULLETPROOF GLASS, AND THEN YOU
GET INTO MONEY, SO THESE ARE
DISCUSSIONS.
THERE'S NO ONE ANSWER.
IT'S A MULTILAYERED ANSWER.
I THINK A LOT OF IT IN OUR
COUNTRY TODAY IS CIVIL
DISCOURSE.
SO I WOULD BEG EVERYONE, PLEASE,
LET'S TRY TO HAVE A CIVIL
DISCURIOUDI
DISCOUR
DISCOURSE.
WHEN YOU FEEL BECAUSE YOU'RE
ANONYMOUS ON THE KEYBOARD YOU
WANT TO TAKE THE GUY OUT YOU
DON'T AGREE WITH, TRY TO HAVE
THESE ANGELS' FACES IN THEIR
MIND BECAUSE YOU'RE NOT HELPING
THEM AND YOU'RE NOT HELPING ALL
THE CHILDREN IN THE UNITED
STATES.
IT'S WHAT I HEARD AT THE VIGIL
AND FROM WHAT I HEARD FROM
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND WHAT I HEARD
AT THE SERVICES TODAY.
EVERYONE WANTS THIS.
NOW WE HAVE TO EXECUTE ON IT.
>> TELL US ABOUT THIS RIBBON.
>> THIS RIBBON COMES FROM OUR
LOCAL GROCERY STORE.
THEY'RE MAKING THEM IN THE
FLORAL DEPARTMENT AND HANDING
THEM OUT TO ANYONE WHO WANTS IT.
THE COLORS REPRESENT SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL.
THESE WERE OUR SCHOOL COLORS --
ARE OUR SCHOOL COLORS.
>> I'VE SEEN OTHER LITTLE
RIBBONS THAT ARE SIMILAR THAT
HAVE A LITTLE ANGEL.
>> I KNOW, I WANT ONE OF THOSE.
>> THE COMMUNITY, YOU KNOW, YOU
WALK AROUND, YOU JUST SEE THESE
LITTLE MEMORIALS THAT ARE
SPRINGING UP AND YOU SEE THESE
NOTES FROM OTHER LITTLE KIDS,
WRITING MESSAGES, WRITING NOTES.
SOME THE -- TWO THE BOYS WERE
BURIED TODAY.
WHO COULD HAVE THOUGHT THAT WE
WOULD BE LIVING THROUGH
SOMETHING LIKE THIS?
>> THERE'S A MEMORIAL ON THE
ENTRANCE COMING INTO TOWN AT THE
SKIN THERE.
THERE'S MEMORIALS AT ANOTHER
SCHOOL THAT HAS NOTHING TO DO
WITH THIS.
IT'S INCREDIBLE, THE OUTPOURING,
IT REALLY IS.
I'M ORIGINALLY FROM THE MIDWEST
AND THE PEOPLE IN MY HOMETOWN OF
KANSAS CITY, THE YOUTPOURING IS
INCREDIBLE, REALLY IS
INCREDIBLE.
AND I CAN'T TELL YOU HOW
TOUCHING THAT IS TO KNOW THAT
PEOPLE THAT I'VE KNOWN MY WHOLE
LIFE THAT ARE NOT JUST IN KANSAS
CITY ANYMORE.
I HAVE A FRIEND IN GERMANY AND
ALL OVER THE WORLD, AND THEY'RE
ALL RESPONDING TO THIS.
THAT'S WHY I THINK IT'S
IMPORTANT THAT WE GET THIS
MESSAGE OUT AND LET'S ALL JOIN
HANDS AND LET'S LEAD WITH LOVE
IN EVERYTHING WE DO.
NOT JUST GETTING THROUGH THIS
TRAGEDY.
BUT REBUILDING WHAT WE WANT THIS
COUNTRY TO DO FOR OUR CHILDREN.
>> HOW ARE THESE PARENTS,
THOUGH, GOING TO -- I CAN ONLY
IMAGINE, YOU KNOW, YOU WERE
THERE AT THE FUNERAL, HOW COULD
THESE PARENTS MOVE FORWARD NOW,
KNOWING WHAT HAS JUST HAPPENED
FRIDAY MORNING?
>> THAT'S A LONG JOURNEY.
I HAVE A LITTLE BIT OF
EXPERIENCE PERSONALLY WITH THAT.
NOT LIKE THIS BUT A LITTLE BIT.
AND IT'S A HOLLOWNESS.
IT'S WEAK KNEES.
IT'S ALL THE HORRIBLE THINGS
EVERYONE IMAGINES.
ALL YOU CAN DO IS TAKE IT A DAY
AT A TIME AND DEPEND ON
EVERYBODY YOU LOVE AND I WOULD
TELL OUR COMMUNITY THAT TWO
WEEKS IS ABOUT THE TIME THAT THE
FAMILY GOES AWAY, AND THAT'S THE
IMPORTANT TIME FOR FRIENDS TO
RUSH IN.
BECAUSE THEN ALL THE FAMILY
MEMBERS ARE OUT OF TOWN.
BUT IT'S GOING TO TAKE A LOT OF
LOVE AND SUPPORT.
IT REALLY IS.
>> IT'S A MOURNING PROCESS.
>> IT'S AWFUL.
>> I CAN ONLY, YOU KNOW, I HAVE
NO IDEA BUT IT'S -- EYE JUST
SEEN A LITTLE BIT OF IT AND IT'S
NORMALLY PARENTS BURY --
CHILDREN BURY THEIR PARENTS.
PARENTS SHOULDN'T BE BURYING
THEIR KIDS, 6-YEAR-OLD AND
7-YEAR-OLD LITTLE KIDS --
>> NO, THAT'S THE HORROR OF
THIS, THE REAL HORROR.
AND THE FACT THAT TEACHERS WERE
PROTECTING PEOPLE.
THAT DAWN TRIED TO STOP HIM.
AND, YOU KNOW, I HEARD ON
ANOTHER INTERVIEW --
>> SHE WAS THE PRINCIPAL OF THE
SCHOOL.
>> I'M SORRY, THE PRINCIPAL,
YES.
I HEARD SOMEONE SAID IF SHE HAD
HAD A GUN LOCKED IN HER OFFICE,
SHE COULD HAVE TAKEN HIM ON.
EXCUSE ME, SHE WAS IN ANOTHER
MEETING, NOT HER OFFICE.
TO GET TO HER OFFICE, SHE WOULD
HAVE HAD TO HAVE GONE THROUGH
THE GUNMAN.
I THINK WE NEED TO LOOK AT WHAT
THESE TEACHERS DID AND NOT JUST
THE ONES WHO PASSED AWAY BUT
THAT WHOLE SCHOOL, I KNOW ALL
THOSE TEACHERS AND WHAT THEY DID
TO PROTECT THEIR CHILDREN AND TO
KEEP THEM SAFE WAS INCREDIBLE.
>> LILLIAN, THANKS FOR WHAT YOU
DID, THANKS FOR INJOINING US,
THANKS FOR SHARING YOUR
THOUGHTS.
>> LEAD WITH LOVE, PLEASE.
>> OUR VIEWERS HERE IN THE
UNITED STATES AND AROUND THE
WORLD, THE WHOLE WORLD IS WATCH
WHAT'S GOING ON.
MAYBE WE'LL LEARN SOME LESSONS.
MAYBE DOWN THE ROAD WE CAN
PREVENT THESE TRAGEDIES FROM
HAPPENING.
LILLIAN, THANKS VERY MUCH.
>>> WHILE EMOTIONS HERE IN
NEWTOWN ARE TOO RAW TO BEGIN
DEBATING WAYS TO STOP GUN
VIOLENCE, THE TALK CERTAINLY
ALREADY STARTING BACK IN
WASHINGTON.
WE'LL HAVE THE LATEST FROM THE
WHITE HOUSE AFTER THIS.
>> I AM VERY MINDFUL THAT MERE
WORDS CANNOT MATCH THE DEPTHS OF
YOUR SORROW, NOR CAN THEY HEAL
YOUR WOUNDED HEARTS.
I CAN ONLY HOPE IT HELPS FOR YOU
TO KNOW THAT YOU'RE NOT ALONE IN
YOUR GRIEF.
THAT OUR WORLD, TOO, HAS BEEN
TORN APART.
THAT ALL ACROSS THIS LAND OF
OURS, WE HAVE WEPT WITH YOU.
WE'VE PULLED OUR CHILDREN TIGHT.
AND YOU MUST KNOW THAT WHATEVER
MEASURE OF COMFORT WE CAN
PROVIDE, WE WILL PROVIDE IT.
WHATEVER PORTION OF SADNESS THAT
WE CAN SHARE WITH YOU TO EASE
THIS HEAVY LOAD, WE WILL GLADLY
BEAR IT.
NEWTOWN, YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
WITH SCOTTRADER
STREAMING QUOTES,
ANY WAY YOU WANT.
FULLY CUSTOMIZE IT
FOR YOUR TRADING PROCESS --
FROM THOUGHT TO TRADE,
ON EVERY SCREEN.
AND ALL IN REAL TIME.
WHICH MAKES IT JUST LIKE
HAVING YOUR OWN TRADING FLOOR,
RIGHT AT YOUR FINGERTIPS.
[ Rodger ] AT SCOTTRADE,
SEVEN DOLLAR TRADES
ARE JUST THE START.
TRY OUR
EASY-TO-USE
SCOTTRADER
STREAMING QUOTES.
IT'S ANOTHER REASON
MORE INVESTORS ARE SAYING...
[ All ]
I'M WITH SCOTTRADE.
YOU'LL ALSO CARE ABOUT
OUR NEW OFFER.
YOU GET ACCESS TO NURSES WHO
CAN HELP WITH YOUR QUESTIONS.
AND YOUR LOVED ONE CAN GET
EXELON PATCH FREE FOR 30 DAYS.
IF THE DOCTOR FEELS
IT'S RIGHT FOR THEM.
IT CANNOT CHANGE
HOW THE DISEASE PROGRESSES.
HOSPITALIZATION
AND RARELY DEATH
HAVE BEEN REPORTED IN PATIENTS
WHO WORE MORE THAN ONE PATCH
AT A TIME.
THE MOST COMMON SIDE EFFECTS
OF EXELON PATCH
ARE NAUSEA, VOMITING,
AND DIARRHEA.
THE LIKELIHOOD AND SEVERITY
OF THESE SIDE EFFECTS
MAY INCREASE
AS THE DOSE INCREASES.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
LOSS OF APPETITE OR WEIGHT.
PATIENTS WHO WEIGH
LESS THAN 110 POUNDS
MAY EXPERIENCE
MORE SIDE EFFECTS.
PEOPLE AT RISK
FOR STOMACH ULCERS
WHO TAKE CERTAIN
OTHER MEDICINES
SHOULD TALK TO THEIR DOCTOR
BECAUSE SERIOUS
STOMACH PROBLEMS
SUCH AS BLEEDING MAY WORSEN.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
SLOW HEART RATE.
THIRTY DAYS OF EXELON PATCH
FREE FOR YOUR LOVED ONE.
ACCESS TO TRAINED NURSES
FOR YOU.
CALL 1-855-999-1399
OR VISIT EXELONPATCHOFFER2.COM.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OUR TENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
>>> THE NEXT PHASE OF A
WRENCHING PAINSTAKING PROCESS
BEGINS.
>> YOU SEE LITTLE COFFINS AND
YOUR HEART HAS TO ACHE.
SO YOU TELL THEM YOU GRIEVE FOR
THEIR LOSS, YOU GIVE THEM A HUG
AND YOU TELL THEM THEIR
COMMUNITY, THEIR STATE AND THEIR
NATION, DARE I SAY THE WHOLE
WORLD, STANDS WITH THEM, AND YOU
HOPE THAT THAT MAKES SOME
DIFFERENCE.
>> THE GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT,
DAN MALLOY, TALKING ABOUT
ATTENDING THE FIRST OF MANY
FUNERALS FOR THE CHILDREN IN THE
DAYS AHEAD.
HE HIMSELF CHOKING BACK TEARS,
RECOUNTING THE PROCESS OF HAVING
TO TELL THE PARENTS OF THOSE WHO
DIED THAT THEIR CHILDREN WEREN'T
COMING BACK TO THEM.
THE GOVERNOR IS CALLING FOR A
MOMENT OF SILENCE THIS FRIDAY AT
9:30 A.M., EXACTLY ONE WEEK TO
THE DAY THIS HORROR BEGAN TO
UNFOLD.
CHURCHES ACROSS THE STATE ARE
BEING ASKED TO CHIME BELLS 26
TIMES IN HONOR OF THOSE WHO ARE
KILLED.
WE WANT TO WELCOME OUR VIEWERS
FROM THE UNITED STATES AND
AROUND THE WORLD.
I'M WOLF BLITZER IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>>> WE BEGIN THIS HOUR WITH NEW
DETAILS.
THEY ARE BEGINNING TO EMERGE
ABOUT THE FIRST PERSON TO BE
KILLED IN THIS HORRIFYING
TRAGEDY, THE MOTHER OF THE
GUNMAN, NANCY LANZA.
SHE WAS HER SON'S FIRST VICTIM.
EVEN THOUGH FRIENDS SAY SHE WENT
TO GREAT LENGTHS TRYING TO HELP
HIM WITH HIS DIFFICULTIES.
THE VERY SAME GUNS NANCY LANZA
KEPT FOR TARGET SHOOTING AND FOR
SAFETY WERE THE ONES USED TO
MURDER HER.
ONE RELATIVE SAYS SHE KEPT THE
WEAPONS FOR SELF-DEFENSE.
>> WE TALKED ABOUT PREPPING AND,
YOU KNOW, ARE YOU READY FOR WHAT
CAN HAPPEN DOWN THE LINE WHEN
THE ECONOMY COLLAPSES.
>> Reporter: FRIENDS SAY SHE
TAUGHT HER SONS HOW TO USE THE
WEAPONS BUT SAYS HER INTEREST IN
GUNS WAS JUST A SAFE HOBBY.
>> I'M SEEN A LOT OF THINGS IN
THE MEDIA ABOUT HER BEING THIS
SURVIVALIST WACO AND THAT WAS
NOT HER AT ALL.
>> Reporter: IRONICALLY, YOUNG
ADAM WAS SO OPPOSED TO KILLING
HE WOULD NOT EVEN EAT ANY MEAT.
HE WAS A VEGAN, SAYS ONE FAMILY
FRIEND.
>> SHE TOLD ME REPEATEDLY HOW
OBSESSED ADAM WAS ABOUT HOLDING
THE GUN THE CORRECT WAY, SO THAT
IT WOULD BE SAFE, THE GUN WAS
UP, AND NEVER POINTING IT AT
ANYBODY.
THAT SAFETY WAS PARAMOUNT
ALWAYS.
>> Reporter: NEWLY OBTAINED
DIVORCE COURT RECORDS SHOW SHE
WAS GIVEN FINAL AUTHORITY TO
MAKE DECISIONS ON HOW THEIR SON
WOULD BE RAISED.
FOR A WHILE, SHE TAUGHT HIM AT
HOME, SAYS AN IN LAW.
>> SHE EVENTUALLY WOUND UP
HOMESCHOOLING HIM.
SHE BATTLED WITH THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT.
IN WHAT CAPACITY, I'M NOT 100%
CERTAIN.
IF IT WAS BEHAVIOR, IT WAS
LEARNING DISABILITIES, I REALLY
DON'T KNOW, BUT HE WAS A VERY,
VERY BRIGHT BOY, HE WAS SMART.
>> Reporter: ACCORDING TO A
FRIEND, TO ACCOMMODATE HIS
PAINFUL SHYNESS, SHE WOULD TELL
ADAM IF ANYONE WAS COMING TO THE
HOUSE SO HE COULD STAY IN HIS
ROOM IF HE WANTED TO.
SHE TRIED HARD TO GET HER SON
HELP, FRIENDS SAY.
SHE WOULD CANCEL WEEKEND PLANSES
IF HE WAS HAVING A TOUGH TIME.
AND SHE WAS THINKING OF SELLING
THE HOUSE IF HER SON FOUND A
PLACE HE WANTED TO STUDY, MAYBE
IN WASHINGTON STATE.
>> SHE WAS READY TO SELL HER
HOUSE AND MOVE WHEREVER ADAM
WANTED TO GO FOR COLLEGE.
>> Reporter: BACK WHEN ADAM WAS
AT SCHOOL, HE WOULD SHUT DOWN
AND WITHDRAW, STARING AT THE
GROUND AND NOT TALKING TO
ANYONE, HIS MOTHER WOULD COME
DOWN TO THE SCHOOL AND COAX HIM
OUT ACCORDING TO THE ADVISER FOR
THE TECH CLUB THE BOY WAS IN.
>> SHE WAS A GOOD MOTHER.
WHO PRETTY MUCH DOTED OVER HER
BOYS.
>> Reporter: DIVORCE RECORDS
SHOW SHE AND HER SONS WERE WELL
PROVIDED FOR.
HER ALIMONY THIS YEAR WAS
SCHEDULED TO BE $289,000.
FRIENDS SAY SHE DID NOT NEED TO
WORK, ALTHOUGH SHE GAVE TO
CHARITIES AND WAS PERSONALLY
GENEROUS HERSELF.
>> SHE WAS JUST -- JUST -- SHE
LIVED A WONDERFUL LIFE.
>> OUR NATIONAL CORRESPONDENT
DEBORAH FEYERICK IS STANDING BY
OUTSIDE THE GUNMAN'S HOUSE WITH
MORE ON THE INVESTIGATION.
WHAT ELSE ARE YOU LEARNING, DEB?
>> WELL, WOLF, WE CAN TELL YOU
THAT SEVERAL UNMARKED POLICE
CARS WENT INTO THE HOME AND HAVE
BEEN GOING INTO THE HOME SINCE
ABOUT 3:00 THIS AFTERNOON.
THE HOME JUST BEHIND ME, THE
ONLY LIGHTS THAT WE CAN SEE THAT
ARE ON ARE ON THE GROUND FLOOR
TO THE RIGHT.
ALL THE OTHER ROOMS, THE SHADES
ARE DRAWN.
VERY DIFFICULT TO SEE WHAT IS
GOING ON INSIDE THAT HOME.
AT LEAST TWO HOMES IN THIS AREA
AS WE WERE DRIVING HERE HAVE
UNMARKED POLICE CARS STATIONED
OUT FRONT.
WE ARE TOLD THAT UNMARKED POLICE
CARS ARE BEING STATIONED AT ALL
THE HOMES OF THOSE WHO LOST
CHILDREN OR ADULTS IN THE
MASSACRE.
THE LANZA HOME IS STILL
CONSIDERED A CRIME SCENE.
AND POLICE SAY THEY HAVE SEIZED
SOME SIGNIFICANT EVIDENCE.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> I CAN ONLY TELL YOU WE SEIZED
EVIDENCE IF, IF, THERE IS
COMPUTER EVIDENCE.
I STRONGLY SAY THAT, IF WE DO
HAVE A COMPUTER CRIMES TEAM, AND
THEN OUR STATE FORENSIC
LABORATORY, THAT ARE EXPERTS IN
RETREATING ANY KIND OF
ELECTRONIC EVIDENCE AND DATA.
>> WE'RE LEARNING A COUPLE OF
THINGS ABOUT ADAM LANZA.
HE WAS IN AND OUT OF VARIOUS
SCHOOLS.
IN 2007, AS A FRESHMAN, THE
SCHOOL SECURITY DIRECTOR THERE
WAS CONCERNED BECAUSE HE WAS --
HE SEEMED SO VULNERABLE THAT THE
DIRECTOR WAS CONCERNED HE WOULD
BE PICKED ON, SO HE TOLD THE
SECURITY OFFICERS TO MAKE SURE
TO KEEP AN EYE ON HIM.
A COUPLE OF YEARS LATER, 2008,
HE ENROLLED IN CLASSES AT A
NEARBY COLLEGE, JUST ABOUT 15 --
COMMUNITY COLLEGE, ABOUT 15
MINUTES FROM HIS HOME.
HE WAS TAKING COMPUTER SCIENCE
AS WELL AS MACRO ECONOMICS,
AMERICAN HISTORY AND GERMAN.
WE SPOKE TO ONE GIRL WHO WAS IN
HIS GERMAN CLASS.
SHE SAID SHE DIDN'T KNOW HIM
VERY WELL BUT AT ONE POINT SHE
SAID, WE'RE GOING OUT, WHY DON'T
YOU JOIN US, HE TOLD HER HE WAS
ONLY 17 AND SHE WAS VERY
SURPRISED BY THAT, SHE DIDN'T
UNDERSTAND JUST HOW YOUNG HE
WAS.
DESCRIBED AS A GENIUS BY ALL
ACCOUNT, VERY QUIET, VERY
PRIVATE.
INVESTIGATORS ARE TRYING TO PUT
TOGETHER PIECES OF THE COMPUTER
HE SMASHED BEFORE HE WENT ON
THIS RAMPAGE, WOLF.
>> WHAT A STORY, DEBORAH
FEYERICK, THANKS VERY MUCH.
THROUGHOUT OUR PROGRAM HERE,
WE'VE BEEN TELLING YOU ABOUT THE
VICTIMS OF THE HORRIFYING
TRAGEDY.
>> WE WANT TO FOCUS ON THE
VICTIMS, NOT -- AS MUCH AS WE
CAN, WOLF, AND TO TELL THEIR
STORIES.
SPECIAL DETAILS ABOUT EACH ONE
OF THEM THAT REALLY HELP DEFINE
WHO THEY WERE.
WE WANT TO GIVE YOU A LOOK AT
SOME OF THEM AND WE'LL CONTINUE
TO DO THAT THROUGHOUT THE SHOW.
ALLISON WYATT WAS QUIET AND A
LITTLE SHY, BUT IF SOMEONE DID
SOMETHING FUNNY, SHE'D BE THE
FIRST ONE TO BURST OUT LAUGHING.
AND JESSE LEWIS, HAD BEEN
LOOKING FORWARD TO MAKING
GINGERBREAD HOUSES AT SCHOOL.
HE LOVED MATH, RIDING HORSES AND
PLAYING AT HIS MOM'S FARM.
VICTORIA SOTO ALWAYS WANTED TO
BE AN EDUCATOR.
JUST LIKE HER AUNT.
THE FIRST GRADE TEACHER LOVED
THE COLOR GREEN AND HER BLACK
LAB, ROXIE.
>> SHE WAS TRULY SELFLESS.
SHE WOULD NOT HESITATE TO SAVE
ANYONE ELSE BEFORE HERSELF AND
ESPECIALLY CHILDREN.
SHE LOVED THEM MORE THAN LIFE
AND SHE WOULD DEFINITELY PUT
HERSELF IN FRONT OF THEM.
ANY DAY.
FOR ANY REASON.
SO IT DOESN'T SURPRISE ANYBODY
THAT KNOWS VICKY THAT SHE DID
THIS.
>> FIRST IN WHAT WILL SADLY BE
DOZENS OF YOUNG SHOOTING VICTIMS
LAID TO REST TODAY.
DETAILS FROM THE FUNERALS.
TWO THEM HAPPENED TODAY.
TWO LITTLE BOYS.
>> TWO LITTLE BOYS.
SO SAD.
>> WE'RE WATCHING WHAT'S GOING
ON AS FAR AS THE FUNERALS ARE
CONCERNED BUT WE'RE -- WANT TO
MAKE SURE THERE'S COMPLETE
PRIVACY AS MUCH AS POSSIBLE FOR
THE GRIEVING FAMILIES.
ALSO, LOCKDOWNS, CAMERAS, IS ANY
OF IT ENOUGH TO KEEP OUR
CHILDREN SAFE AT SCHOOL?
WE'LL TAKE A CLOSER LOOK AT THAT
AS WELL.
TO THE BEST VACATION
SPOT ON EARTH.
(ALL) THE GULF!
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHICH OF
OUR GREAT STATES FOLKS VISIT.
MISSISSIPPI,
ALABAMA,
LOUISIANA
OR FLORIDA,
THEY'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
SHAUL, YOUR ALABAMA
HOSPITALITY IS INCREDIBLE.
THANKS, KAREN.
LOVE YOUR MISSISSIPPI OUTDOORS.
I VOTE FOR YOUR
FLORIDA BEACHES, DAWN.
BILL, THIS LOUISIANA
SEAFOOD IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR ON THE GULF,
WE'VE DECIDED TO PUT
ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
NOW IS THE PERFECT TIME TO
VISIT ANYONE OF OUR STATES.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE, GO FISHING
OR JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
WE'VE GOT COASTLINE TO EXPLORE
AND WILDLIFE TO PHOTOGRAPH.
AND THERE'S WORLD CLASS DINING
WITH OUR WORLD FAMOUS SEAFOOD.
SO FOR A GREAT VACATION
THIS YEAR, COME TO THE GULF.
ITS ALL FABULOUS BUT
I GIVE FLORIDA THE EDGE.
RIGHT AFTER MISSISSIPPI.
YOU MEAN ALABAMA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
THIS INVITATION IS
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP
AND ALL OF US WHO
CALL THE GULF HOME.
[ Male Announcer ] IF SOMEONE
ASKS WHAT IT FEELS LIKE
TO DRIVE A JEEP GRAND CHEROKEE,
TELL THEM
IT'S LIKE BEING NESTLED
IN AN EIGHT-WAY, ADJUSTABLE,
HEATED AND VENTILATED SEAT
SURROUNDED BY A 500-WATT
SOUND SYSTEM
WHILE FLOATING ON A SUSPENSION
MADE OF BILLOWY CLOUDS.
OR YOU COULD JUST HAND THEM
YOUR KEYS.
♪
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>>> THEY ARE BEGINNING THE
HEARTBREAKING TASK OF BURYING
THE DEAD TODAY.
6-YEAR-OLDS NOAH POZNER AND JACK
PITTO WERE BOTH LAID TO REST.
NOAH WAS SAID TO BE A CHARMING
LITTLE BOY WHO LOVED PLAYING
WITHED SIBLINGS, PARTICULARLY
HIS SISTER.
CNN'S KYUNG LAH HAS THE
DIFFICULT ASSIGNMENT OF COVERING
JACK'S FUNERAL FOR US.
SHE'S JOINING US NOW WITH SOME
OF THE DETAILS.
WE WANT TO BE TOTALLY RESPECTFUL
OF THE PRIVACY OF THESE FAMILIES
WHO ARE GOING THROUGH HELL RIGHT
NOW, KYUNG.
>> IT'S VERY, VERY DIFFICULT.
WE DID WANT TO RESPECT THE
FAMILY'S WISHES.
THE FAMILY WANTED AS PRIVATE A
SERVICE AS THEY COULD HAVE, AS
PRIVATE A SERVICE AS THEY COULD
HAVE WHEN YOU CONSIDER HOW MANY
REPORTERS ARE HERE, HOW MANY
CAMERAS ARE INTERESTED IN THIS.
FROM THE DISTANCE WE WERE
STANDING AWAY FROM THE CHURCH,
WE COULD SEE THAT THIS WAS A
VERY DIFFICULT DAY FOR THE
FAMILY, THE FRIENDS, OF THIS
LITTLE BOY.
A 6-YEAR-OLD BOY WHO WAS IN THE
FIRST GRADE.
THE PEOPLE ARRIVING NOT THE
USUAL PEOPLE YOU SEE AT A
FUNERAL.
YOUNG FAMILIES.
A LOT OF YOUNG CHILDREN.
THE CHILDREN WHO ARRIVED WERE
WEARING NEWTOWN WRESTLING
SHIRTS, LONG SLEEVE SHIRTS AND
SWEATSHIRTS.
ONE LITTLE BOY WAS WEARING A
MEDAL.
THE SIGNIFICANCE OF THAT
MEDAL -- I'VE SPOKEN TO PEOPLE
IN THE WRESTLING COMMUNITY HERE
IN CONNECTICUT.
ONE TOWN THAT'S NEARBY SAID THAT
JACK HAD JUST COMPETED IN HIS
FIRST WRESTLING MATCH.
HIS FIRST OFFICIAL WRESTLING
MATCH.
AND HAD WON HIS FIRST MEDAL.
THIS LITTLE BOY LOVED SPORTS BUT
HIS FIRST LOVE WAS FOOTBALL AND
HIS IDOL WAS NEW YORK GIANT
PLAYER VICTOR CRUZ.
NOW, THAT MESSAGE GOT TO THE
FOOTBALL PLAYER.
HE DECIDED THAT HE WANTED TO PUT
THE LITTLE BOY'S NAME ON HIS
CLEATS AND HIS GLOVES.
HE TWEETED OUT A PICTURE OF IT.
HE THEN CALLED JACK'S FAMILY.
HERE'S WHAT CRUZ TOLD REPORTERS.
>> IT WAS EMOTIONAL, MAN, YOU
KNOW, I WAS FIGHTING BACK TEARS
A LITTLE BIT TO DO IT.
IT FELT GOOD TO HONOR A FAMILY
THAT WAS GOING THROUGH SO MUCH.
JUST THE THOUGHT OF YOUR LITTLE
ONE OR YOUR CHILD, YOUR SON OR
DAUGHTER, GOING THROUGH
SOMETHING LIKE THIS, YOU KNOW,
IT WAS JUST UNBELIEVABLE TO EVEN
LISTEN TO ON THE NEWS.
THAT NIGHT, I PUT MY DAUGHTER IN
THE BED WITH ME.
>> THE FAMILY IS REPORTEDLY
BURYING THEIR SON IN A VICTOR
CRUZ JERSEY.
A VERY DIFFICULT DAY.
JUST THE VERY FIRST OF WHAT WILL
BE MANY MORE FUNERALS, WOLF.
>> HOW SAD IS THIS, UNBELIEVABLY
SAD.
THANKS, KYUNG LAH, FOR THAT.
AS THESE FIRST OF WHAT WILL BE
MANY FUNERAL SERVICES GET UNDER
WAY, MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS ARE
POPPING UP AROUND THIS TOWN.
CNN'S DON LEMON IS JOINING US
FROM ONE OF THEM.
JUST A LITTLE BIT DOWN THE ROAD
FROM WHERE I AM RIGHT NOW.
DON, THESE MEMORIALS REALLY HAVE
A WAY OF LETTING PEOPLE EXPRESS
THEIR EMOTIONS.
THIS IS A HUGE, HUGE TRAGEDY.
>> YEAH, IT IS A HUGE TRAGEDY.
THIS ONE IS THE BIGGEST ONE.
THIS IS THE HEART OF THE
COMMUNITY HERE.
THERE'S A BAND THAT'S HERE
THAT'S BEEN COMING BY EVERY DAY.
THEY'VE BEEN PLAYING.
A SIGN IN FRONT SAYS "REMEMBER
THE CHILDREN."
MEMBERS OF THE GROUP AS WELL.
I WANT TO TALK TO SOME OF THESE
FOLKS.
LOOK AT THIS BIG TEDDY BEAR.
IS THIS FROM YOUR OWN OR DID YOU
BUY IT?
>> FROM MY CHILDREN, SOMETHING
THAT THEY'VE HAD.
>> WHY DID YOU COME OUT?
>> IT'S JUST HARD TO NOT THINK
ABOUT WHAT'S GOING ON HERE.
WE DO LIVE IN CONNECTICUT ABOUT
20 MINUTES FROM HERE.
A COUPLE OF MY FRIENDS, MYSELF,
JUST WANTED TO TAKE A RIDE.
>> THIS HAS BEEN IN YOUR FAMILY.
OBVIOUSLY, IT MEANS A LOT.
YOU'RE GOING TO LEAVE IT HERE.
>> WE ARE.
>> THANK YOU, EILEEN, WE REALLY
APPRECIATE IT.
YOU GUYS ARE FROM SANDY HOOK,
WHERE YOU FROM?
>> MY PARENTS LIVE IN SANDY
HOOK.
>> WE'RE ORIGINALLY FROM HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
>> WHERE DO YOU LIVE NOW?
>> WE LIVE IN OXFORD,
CONNECTICUT.
>> WHY ARE YOU HERE?
>> WE'RE HERE TO GIVE OUR
SUPPORT AND OUR -- MOSTLY OUR
PRAYERS TO THE FAMILIES AND THE
COMMUNITY.
JUST HERE FOR THE SUPPORT FOR
EVERYBODY.
>> WHEN YOU LOOK AT HOW BIG THIS
MEMORIAL IS, WHAT DO YOU THINK?
>> IT'S AMAZING, YOU KNOW, YOU
FORGET ABOUT -- YOU HAVE TO
REMEMBER THERE'S SO MANY GOOD
PEOPLE IN THE WORLD AND THIS IS
A GOOD REMINDER.
IT'S AMAZING HOW MUCH STUFF
THERE REALLY IS.
>> HAS THIS HELP ED?
>> YES, I'M GLAD I CAME DOWN
HERE, IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
>> ARE YOU GOING TO PUT THE
WREATH HERE?
>> YES, I AM GOING TO PUT THE
WREATH HERE.
>> WHERE ARE YOU FROM?
>> WE'RE FROM PUTNAM,
CONNECTICUT.
>> DOES THIS HELP, TO COME OUT?
>> YES, IT DOES, BECAUSE WEEM
WATCHED IT ALL WEEKEND AND IT'S
JUST SO PAINFUL TO SEE -- WHAT
HAPPENED TO THESE ANGELS AND TO
THESE WONDERFUL TEACHERS, AND
THIS IS OUR WAY OF EXPRESSING
HOW SORROWFUL WE FEEL FOR ALL OF
THEM.
>> YOU THINK THIS COMMUNITY WILL
EVER BE THE SAME?
>> I THINK IT WILL REBOUND.
IT'S THE STATE OF CONNECTICUT
AND THE STATE OF CONNECTICUT IS
A GREAT STATE IN OUR UNION AND I
THINK THE COMMUNITY WILL REBOUND
AND WITH ALL OUR PRAYERS AND
EVERYONE'S PRAYERS, YES.
I ALSO WANT TO THANK CNN FOR THE
WONDERFUL JOB YOU DONE IN THIS
NEWSCAST.
I WATCHED YOU ALL WEEKEND, ALL
DAY TODAY, AND YOU HAVE DONE AN
AMAZING COMPASSIONATE JOB.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> WELL, THANK YOU.
>> -- FOR BRINGING THIS TO THE
COUNTRY.
>> THANK YOU, WE REALLY
APPRECIATE IT.
EVERYONE HERE HAS BEEN AMAZING
AND SO WELCOMING SO WE WANT TO
BE, YOU KNOW, COGNIZANT OF THAT
AND RESPECT YOU GUYS AND NOT BE
INTRUSIVE.
APPRECIATE IT.
THERE'S SO MUCH EMOTION GOING ON
OVER HERE.
DO YOU MIND IF WE TALK TO YOU?
>> NO, THAT'S FINE.
STAY WITH ME, LISA.
MY NAME IS GLORIA.
>> AND YOU'RE HERE?
>> I'M HERE BECAUSE I HAVE FOUR
GRANDCHILDREN.
AND I WAS ABLE TO ATTEND MY
SON'S -- HE'S IN FIRST GRADE,
AND HE HAD HIS CHRISTMAS CONCERT
TONIGHT, AND THERE PRETTY MUCH
WASN'T A DRY EYE THERE.
I MET THIS WONDERFUL WOMAN HERE
FROM ALABAMA.
SO PEOPLE ARE COMING FROM ALL
OTHER.
>> THEY ARE.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
OUR HEARTS ARE WITH YOU.
THANK YOU.
WE REALLY APPRECIATE IT.
WOLF, NOT MUCH TO SAY.
THE EMOTION IS PALPABLE HERE.
AND THIS -- THIS MEMORIAL NOW
WHICH IS THE HEART OF THE
COMMUNITY IS WHERE PEOPLE COME
AND PEOPLE ARE COMING AND
THEY'RE SHARING THEIR FEELINGS
AND WE'RE HERE WITH THEM AND
WE'RE GIVING THEM A VOICE WE
FEEL.
>> SO MANY PEOPLE ARE GRIEVING.
SO MANY PEOPLE ARE MOURNING.
AND THIS UNFORTUNATELY IS GOING
TO STAY FOR SOME TIME TO COME.
SOME PEOPLE WILL NEVER, EVER,
EVER BE ABLE TO GET OVER THERE.
THAT'S TOTALLY UNDERSTANDABLE.
THE TRAGEDY IS ENORMOUS.
WE'RE GOING TO COME BACK TO YOU.
WANT TO GET MORE OF THESE
STORIES.
WHAT PEOPLE ARE SAYING WHO ARE
COMING TO TALK ABOUT WHAT'S
GOING ON.
WE'LL TAKE A QUICK BREAK.
MUCH MORE RIGHT AFTER THIS.
I NEED YOU.
I FEEL SO ALONE.
BUT YOU'RE NOT
ALONE.
I KNEW YOU'D COME.
LIKE I COULD STAY AWAY.
YOU KNOW I CAN'T DO THIS
WITHOUT YOU.
YOU'LL NEVER HAVE TO.
YOU'RE ALWAYS THERE
FOR ME.
SHH!
I'LL GET YOU
A RENTAL CAR.
I COULD ALSO USE
AN UMBRELLA.
FALL IN LOVE WITH
PROGRESSIVE'S CLAIMS SERVICE.
WE BELIEVE THE MORE YOU KNOW,
THE BETTER YOU TRADE.
SO WE HAVE ONGOING WEBINARS
AND INTERACTIVE LEARNING,
PLUS, IN-BRANCH SEMINARS
AT OVER 500 LOCATIONS,
WHERE OUR DEDICATED SUPPORT
TEAMS HELP YOU KNOW MORE
SO YOUR MONEY CAN DO MORE.
[ Rodger ] AT SCOTTRADE,
SEVEN DOLLAR TRADES
ARE JUST THE START.
OUR TEAMS HAVE THE
INFORMATION YOU WANT
WHEN YOU NEED IT.
IT'S ANOTHER REASON
MORE INVESTORS ARE SAYING...
[ All ]
I'M WITH SCOTTRADE.
>>> IN THE WAKE OF THIS ENORMOUS
TRAGEDY HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, PEOPLE IN
COMMUNITIES ALL ACROSS THE
COUNTRY ARE WONDERING WHAT CAN
BE DONE.
GUN CONTROL ADVOCATES ARE
WONDERING WILL THIS BE ENOUGH TO
GET CONGRESS TO ACT.
OUR SENIOR CONGRESSIONAL
CORRESPONDENT DANA BASH IS
JOINING US NOW FROM CAPITOL
HILL.
DANA, WHAT ARE YOU SENSING THEIR
ATTITUDES AS FAR AS GUNS ARE
CONCERNED, ARE ATTITUDES
SHIFTING?
>> THOSE WHO DON'T WANT TO DO
ANYTHING STILL TO RESTRICT GUN
RIGHTS THEY'RE BEING CAREFUL NOT
TO SAY ANYTHING UNTIL THE
RAWNESS OF THIS TRAGEDY GOES
AWAY OR SUBSIDES A LITTLE.
TO ANSWER YOUR QUESTION, YES,
ATTITUDES ARE SHIFTING IN A
REMARKABLE WAY IN FAVOR OF MORE
GUN CONTROL.
>> READ COMMUNICATION OF THE
SENATE --
>> Reporter: ON THE FLOOR OF THE
SENATE, A TRIBUTE TO THE VICTIMS
OF THE UNSPEAKABLE SHOOTING
SPREE.
>> I NOW ASK THE UNITED STATES
SENATE OBSERVE A MOMENT OF
SILENCE FOR THE VICTIMS OF THE
SANDY HOOK TRAGEDY.
>> Reporter: AND IN AN UNUSUAL
MOVE, THE SENATE CHAPLAIN PRAYED
FOR ACTION.
>> MAKE OUR LAWMAKERS WILLING TO
ACT PROMPTLY.
>> Reporter: IT'S A STARK
ILLUSTRATION OF HOW MASS MURDER
OF SMALL CHILDREN HAS CHANGED
THE TONE.
ESPECIALLY AMONG DEMOCRATS.
RELUCTANT IN RECENT YEARS TO
TALK ABOUT GUN CONTROL.
>> YOU KNOW, THAT -- IT'S
CHANGED ME.
>> Reporter: LAWMAKERS OF EITHER
PARTY ACTIVELY SUPPORT AND
CAMPAIGN ON GUN RIGHTS AS MUCH
AS VIRGINIA DEMOCRAT JOE
MANCHIN.
>> I'LL TAKE DEAD AIM.
>> Reporter: NOW, MANCHIN, WHO
HAS AN "A" RATING FROM THE
POWERFUL RIFLE ASSOCIATION,
WANTS NEW GUN RESTRICTIONS.
>> I DON'T KNOW OF ANYBODY THAT
GOES HUNTING WITH AN ASSAULT
RIFLE.
I DON'T KNOW PEOPLE THAT NEED
10, 20, 30-ROUND CLIPS.
>> YOU'RE COMMITTED TO CHANGE?
>> I'M COMMITTED TO BRINGING THE
DIALOGUE THAT WILL BRING A TOTAL
CHANGE.
>> Reporter: MANCHIN EVEN CALLED
DEMOCRAT DIANNE FEINSTEIN
USUALLY ON THE OPPOSITE SIDE OF
THE GUN ISSUE, LOOKING TO WORK
TOGETHER, RIGHT BEFORE WE TALKED
TO HER.
>> HE AND I WILL SIT DOWN, WE'LL
GO OVER THIS LEGISLATION.
>> Reporter: THAT LEGISLATION
WOULD REINSTATE THE ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN, WHICH LAPSED IN
2004.
WHY DO YOU THINK THIS MOMENT MAY
BE DIFFERENT?
>> BECAUSE I THINK IT'S A
LOGICAL CONTINUUM.
IF THERE SHOULD BE A SAFE PLACE
IN AMERICA, IT'S AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
HERE IN THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
LOOK WHAT HAPPENED.
6-YEAR-OLDS WITH 3 TO 11 BULLETS
FROM THIS BUSHMASTER IN THEIR
BODY, 20 OF THEM.
IS THIS AMERICA?
I DON'T THINK SO.
>> Reporter: TO BE SURE, GUN
CONTROL LEGISLATION HAS STALLED
OVER THE PAST DECADE LARGELY
BECAUSE DEMOCRATS CONCLUDED IT
WAS BAD POLITICS.
ESPECIALLY FOR VULNERABLE
DEMOCRATS IN CONSERVATIVE
STATES.
SOME HALF A DOZEN OF THOSE
MODERATE SENATE DEMOCRATS FACE
VOTERS IN THE NEXT ELECTION, AND
NONE HAS EMBRACED NEW GUN
RESTRICTIONS YET.
THE NRA, WHICH TRADITIONALLY HAS
THE POWER TO HURT DEMOCRATS IN
RED STRAIGATES WHO SUPPORT GUN
CONTROL, HAS BEEN NOTABLY
SILENT.
AFTER SHOOTING SPREE IN THE
MOVIE THEATER IN COLORADO,
SEVERAL LAWMAKERS FROM RED
STATES TOLD ME THEY DEFINITELY
FEEL THE NRA'S CLOUT STILL HERE
ON CAPITOL HILL, AND JUST BEING,
WOLF, IN SENATOR FEINSTEIN'S
FRONT OFFICE FOR FIVE MINUTES, I
COULD SEE THE PHONES RINGING OFF
THE HOOK ABOUT HER CALL TO
REVIVE OR REINSTATE THE ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN.
AT LEAST MAKE THAT THE FIRST
PIECE OF LEGISLATION IN THE NEW
CONGRESS BUT IT IS VERY
INTERESTING IT'S NOT JUST THE
NRA KEEPING MUM RIGHT NOW,
REPUBLICAN SENATORS, MOST OF
THEM WHO WE'VE TALKED TO, ARE
DECLINING INTERVIEW REQUESTS.
THEY JUST DON'T WANT TO TALK
ABOUT IT QUITE YET.
>> WE'LL SEE WHAT HAPPENS DOWN
THE ROAD.
DANA, THANK YOU.
>>> THIS UNIMAGINABLE TRAGEDY.
ADULTS ARE DESPERATELY
STRUGGLING TO COMPREHEND, SO HOW
DO YOU POSSIBLY BEGIN TO TALK
ABOUT THIS WITH YOUR CHILDREN?
OUR OWN DR. SANJAY GUPTA, HE'S
GETTING SOME NEW INFORMATION FOR
US.
HE'LL BE JOINING US SHORTLY.
FR.
♪
...COULD END
WITH ADDING A CLOSE FRIEND.
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE RHYTHM OF LIFE.
[ whistle blowing ]
WHERE DO YOU HEAR THAT BEAT?
CAMPBELL'S HEALTHY REQUEST SOUP
LETS YOU HEAR IT...
IN YOUR HEART.
[ basketball bouncing ]
HEART HEALTHY.
GREAT TASTE.
MMM...
[ Male Announcer ] SOUNDS GOOD.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
but with ADVAIR,
I'm breathing better.
So now I can be in
the scene.
ADVAIR is
clinically proven to help
significantly improve
lung function.
Unlike most COPD medications,
ADVAIR contains both an
anti-inflammatory
and a
long-acting bronchodilator
working together to help improve
your lung function all day.
ADVAIR won't
replace fast-acting inhalers
for sudden symptoms
and should not be used more
than twice a day.
People with
COPD taking ADVAIR
may have a higher chance
of pneumonia.
ADVAIR may increase your
risk of osteoporosis
and some eye problems.
Tell your doctor
if you have a heart condition
or high blood pressure before
taking ADVAIR.
If you're still
having difficulty breathing,
ask your doctor if including
ADVAIR could help
improve your lung function.
Get your
first full
prescription
free
and save
on refills
at
ADVAIRcopd.com.
>>> WE'RE CONTINUING TO REMEMBER
MORE OF THE VICTIM, OF THIS
HORRIBLE MASSACRE.
>> WE'LL BRING YOU SOME OF THEIR
STORIES.
LIVES WERE CUT TOO SHORT FAR TOO
EARLY.
DANIEL BARDEN PLAYED THE DRUMS
IN A FAMILY BAND.
HE LOST HIS TWO FRONT TEETH IN
HIS FEARLESS PURSUIT OF LIFE.
ANNE MARIE MURPHY'S MOTHER SAYS
THE SPECIAL EDUCATION TEACHER
DIED DOING WHAT SHE LOVED,
SERVING CHILDREN AND SERVING
GOD.
AND JESSICA REKOS LOVED
EVERYTHING ABOUT HORSES.
SHE HOPED TO GET ONE WHEN SHE
TURNED 10.
SHE ASKED SANTA FOR COWGIRL
BOOTS AND A HAT.
>> SHE WAS A BALL OF FIRE.
>> OUR LITTLE CEO WE CALLED HER.
SHE WAS THE BOSS.
>> CHILDREN ALL ACROSS THE
COUNTRY WERE BACK AT SCHOOL
TODAY WITH THE TRAGEDY HERE IN
CONNECTICUT.
MOST LIKELY NOT FAR FROM ANY
PARENT'S MIND.
OUR OWN LISA SYLVESTER IS
STAKING A CLOSER LOOK AT SCHOOL
SECURITY AND WHETHER ENOUGH IS
BEING DONE TO KEEP OUR CHILDREN
SAFE.
>> Reporter: THEY SAY WHEN YOU
BECOME A PARENT THAT A LITTLE
BIT OF YOUR HEART LIVES OUTSIDE
OF YOU.
FOR MANY PARENTS, THIS TRAGEDY,
IS HAS HIT THEIR WORST FEAR.
HOW DO YOU KEEP YOUR KIDS SAFE
WHEN THEY ARE AWAY FROM YOU?
>> HAVE A GOOD DAY.
>> YOU TRY NOT TO THINK ABOUT
IT.
>> Reporter: THIS DAY, SHE HAS A
HARD TIME HOLDING BACK THE
TEARS.
>> IT'S HEARTBREAKING.
IT'S -- IT'S VERY DIFFICULT TO
IMAGINE AND I CAN'T IMAGINE
BEING ONE OF THOSE PARENTS.
>> Reporter: WHAT HAPPENED IN
NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT COULD HAVE
HAPPENED IN ANY TOWN.
IT'S ONE OF THOSE QUIET FEARS
PARENTS HAVE.
PAGE ANDERSON OF MONTGOMERY
COUNTY, MARYLAND, HAS A
6-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER.
>> MY DAUGHTER TOLD ME THEY DID
A DRILL LAST WEEK SO I THINK
THEY DO THEM ON A REGULAR BASIS.
WHEN YOU CAN'T PREPARE FOR EVERY
EVENTUALITY.
>> Reporter: SCHOOLS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY ARE REVIEWING THEIR
SCHOOL SAFETY PROGRAMS THAT HAVE
BEEN IN PLACE SINCE COLUMBINE.
HIGH SCHOOLS IN ALEXANDRIA,
VIRGINIA, HAVE TRAINED POLI
POLICPOLICE OF
OFFICERS ON CAMPUS.
MIDDLE SCHOOLS REQUIRE ALL
VISITORS TO BE BUZZED AND SIGNED
IN.
FOR ALEXANDRIA'S SCHOOL
SUPERINTENDENT, THIS IS DEEPLY
PERSONAL, AS A FATHER AND
GRANDFATHER.
HE VISITED A KINDERGARTEN AND
FIRST GRADE CLASS TO OFFER ANY
NEEDED COMFORT AND REASSURANCE.
>> IT'S REALLY EMOTIONAL.
I DIDN'T THINK IT WOULD BE AT
FIRST.
JUST GOING INTO THE CLASSROOMS,
LOOKING AT THOSE BABIES, LOOKING
AT THOSE WONDERFUL CHILDREN,
LOOKING AT THEIR FACES, AND
REALIZED THERE BUT FOR THE GRACE
OF GOD OR SOMEBODY ELSE COULD BE
OUR KIDS HERE IN ALEXANDRIA.
>> Reporter: THE SHOOTING IN
NEWTOWN IS OPENING U A NEW
CONVERSATION.
HOW MUCH SECURITY AT SCHOOLS IS
ENOUGH.
SHOULD THERE BE ARMED GUARDS AT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS, IN
PRESCHOOLS?
METAL DETECTORS?
SCHOOL SIPSYCHOLOGISTS SAY THER
HAS TO BE A BALANCE.
>> WE KNOW HAVING METAL
DETECTORS AND SECURITY PEOPLE
OUTSIDE THE FRONT OF THE SCHOOL,
NOT ONLY WOULD MOST PARENTS NOT
WANT TO DROP OFF THEIR
6-YEAR-OLD AT SCHOOL LIKE THAT,
THAT TYPICALLY DOESN'T DECREASE
VIOLENCE AND IT CAN ACTUALLY
DECREASE THE PERCEIVED SENSE OF
SAFETY IN THAT SCHOOL.
>> Reporter: SCHOOL SPSYCHOLOGIT
ALSO SAY WHAT KIDS NEED NOW IS A
GREATER SENSE OF SECURITY.
THAT WHEN THEY GET ON THAT
SCHOOL BUS, THEY WILL RETURN
HOME.
AND SOME OF THE THINGS THE
SCHOOL CAN DO, THE NATIONAL
ASSOCIATION OF SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGISTS SAYS IF THEY DON'T
ALREADY HAVE ONE, SCHOOLS SHOULD
ESTABLISH A CRISIS RESPONSE TEAM
TO DEAL WITH ANY EMERGENCY.
THEY SHOULD ALSO COMMUNICATE
WITH PARENTS AND EXPLAIN WHAT
KIND OF STEPS ARE BEING DONE TO
KEEP CHILDREN SAFE.
THEY SHOULD REVIEW ALL SAFETY
POLICIES AND HAVE ADEQUATE
COUNSELORS ON HAND TO DEAL WITH
ANY OF THE EMOTIONAL NEEDS THAT
CHILDREN AND THE TEACHERS MIGHT
HAVE.
WOLF.
>> TELL YOU, PEOPLE ARE GOING TO
BE STUDYING HOW BEST TO DEAL
WITH SECURITY AT SCHOOLS A LOT.
THEY SHOULD.
BECAUSE THIS TRAGEDY IS
ENORMOUS.
LISA, THANKS VERY MUCH.
>> THANK YOU, LISA.
THE FAMILY OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL PRINCIPAL
WE'VE HEARD SO MUCH ABOUT HER,
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, SAYS SHE WENT
DOWN IN THE BLAZE GLORY THAT
TRULY REPRESENT WHO SHE WAS.
SHE WAS BELOVED BY HER STUDENTS
AND KNOWN FOR ALWAYS HAVING A
SMILE ON HER FACE.
CNN NATIONAL CORRESPONDENT GARY
TUCHMAN HAD THE CHANCE TO SIT
DOWN WITH DAWN'S HUSBAND,
CHILDREN AND STEPCHILDREN, FOR
WHAT WAS A VERY EMOTIONAL, VERY
MOVING INTERVIEW.
>> Reporter: PRINCIPAL DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG WAS QUITE A BIT
YOUNGER THAN HER HUSBAND GEORGE.
WHEN THEY GOT MARRIED TEN YEARS
AGO, SHE WITH TWO DAUGHTERS AND
HE WITH THREE, DAWN WAS MARRYING
HER BOSS.
>> SHE WAS THE ASSISTANT
PRINCIPAL.
I WAS THE SEVENTH GRADE MATH
TEACHER.
>> Reporter: GEORGE MADE THE
DECISION THE TIME HAD COME TO
PROPOSE.
>> SHE TURNED ME DOWN FIVE
TIMES.
>> Reporter: WHAT HAPPENED THE
SIXTH TIME?
>> THE SIXTH TIME, I WAITED
UNTIL IT WASN'T SO RUSHED.
>> Reporter: HE POPPED THE
QUESTION ON A SAILBOAT THEY
BOUGHT TOGETHER.
>> WE GOT MARRIED.
>> Reporter: BETH, AMY AND ANN
ARE GEORGE'S FIRST DAUGHTERS
FROM HIS FIRST MARRIAGE.
ERICA IS DAWN'S DAUGHTER FROM
HER FIRST MARRIAGE.
HER OTHER DAUGHTER TINA WAS OUT
WHILE WE WERE AT THE HOUSE.
THEY ARE A BLENDED BUT VERY
CLOSE FAMILY WITH 11
GRANDCHILDREN.
>>CY BUILT THIS BEAUTIFUL HOUSE
IN THE ADIRONDACKS.
THE DREAM WAS IT WAS GOING TO BE
DAWN'S HOUSE BECAUSE I WAS GOING
TO DIE, BECAUSE I'M MUCH OLDER
THAN DAWN.
DAWN'S GRANDCHILDREN AND ALL
THESE CHILDREN COULD USE THE
HOUSE ON THE LAKE AND IT WOULD
BE WONDERFUL.
WE BUILT ROOMS DOWNSTAIRS FOR
KIDS.
IT WAS GOING TO BE DAWN'S HOUSE
ULTIMATELY.
WITH ALL THE GRANDCHILDREN.
ALL THE CHILDREN.
AND NOW IT'S ME.
I DON'T THINK I CAN DO THAT.
>> Reporter: I WANT TO
REITERATE, YOUR BEAUTIFUL
DAUGHTERS, YOUR SON-IN-LAWS,
YOUR BEAUTIFUL GRANDCHILDREN,
EVERYONE WILL BE HERE TO TAKE
CARE OF YOU.
>> MY JOB IS TO TAKE CARE OF
THEM.
>> Reporter: IT'S ALL RIGHT IF
SOMEONE TAKES CARE OF YOU.
>> NO ONE HAS EVER HAD TO TAKE
CARE OF ME.
>> Reporter: IN THE MIDDLE OF
THE DAY FRIDAY, THIS IS HOW
GEORGE FOUND OUT WHAT HAPPENED.
>> WELL, ONE OF THE KIDS CAME UP
WITH A COMPUTER.
AND SAID, SOMETHING'S HAPPENING
AT SANDY HOOK SCHOOL AND YOUR
WIFE'S BEEN KILLED.
>> Reporter: GEORGE RACED OUT OF
SCHOOL AND INTO A NIGHTMARE.
LIKE ALL THE FAMILIES OF
VICTIMS, THEY WANT TO KNOW MORE.
ON THIS DAY, THEY HAVE LEARNED
MORE.
TWO TEACHERS SURVIVED.
TOLD GEORGE THEY WERE HAVING A
MEETING WITH DAWN WHEN THE SHOTS
STARTED RINGING OUT.
>> DAWN PUT HERSELF IN JEOPARDY.
I HAD BEEN ANGRY ABOUT THAT,
ANGRY, UNTIL JUST NOW, TODAY,
WHEN I MET TWO WOMEN THAT SHE
TOLD TO GO UNDER SHELTER WHILE
SHE ACTUALLY CONFRONTED THE
GUNMAN AND SHE COULD NOT -- SHE
COULD HAVE AVOIDED THAT.
BUT SHE DIDN'T.
I KNEW SHE WOULDN'T.
SO I'M NOT ANGRY ANYMORE.
I'M NOT ANGRY.
I'M NOT ANGRY ANYMORE.
I'M JUST VERY SAD.
SAD.
SOMEBODY SHOT OUT THE WINDOW.
SOMEBODY CAME IN, INTO THE --
NOT INTO THE OFFICE BUT INTO THE
BUILDING.
DAWN TOLD US TO GO HIDE.
AND SHE AND ONE OTHER TEACHER
RAN OUT.
AND ACTUALLY TRIED TO SUBDUE THE
KILLER.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE THAT COMES
FROM.
DAWN WAS, WHAT, 5'2".
>> Reporter: EVERYONE HERE IS SO
PROUD.
NO ONE MORE SO THAN ERICA, WHO
SAID HER MOM WAS ALWAYS THERE
FOR HER DAUGHTERS.
>> EITHER GAME, SHE WAS THERE.
EVERY GAME, EVERY PRACTICE.
MY SISTER'S CHEER LEAD, SHE WAS
THERE, EVERY DANCE COMPETITION.
SHE WAS DOING HOMEWORK ON THE
BLEACHERS, BUT SHE WAS THERE.
AND SHE WAS MY ROCK.
MY ROCK.
>> Reporter: AND NOW SHE IS A
HERO TOO.
THE FINAL THING I WANT TO ASK
YOU IS WHAT WOULD YOU SAY TO
YOUR MOM RIGHT NOW?
>> COME BACK.
JUST COME BACK.
>> DAWN HOCHSPRUNG'S BIGGEST
ACCOMPLISHMENTS AS PRINCIPAL WAS
OVERSEEING THE INSTALLATION OF A
NEW SECURITY SYSTEM REQUIRING
EVERY VISITOR TO RING THE FRONT
DOORBELL AFTER THE SCHOOL DOORS
LOCKED AT 9:30 EVERY MORNING.
HER HUSBAND, HER FAMILY, THEY
JUST SEEM, UNDERSTANDABLY, SHELL
SHOCKED.
>> YEAH.
THE SHOOTER IN THIS CASE FIRED
HIS WAY IN, THROUGH THE GLASS,
FORCED HIS ENTRY.
>> FORCED HIS WAY IN AND THEN
HEADED FOR THE FIRST GRADE
CLASSROOMS.
>> A PARENT'S GRADE FIVE YEARS
LATER.
A FATHER OF A VICTIM IN THE
VIRGINIA TECH TRAGEDY SHARES HIS
LESSONS OF SURVIVING A TRAGEDY.
>>> FIVE YEARS AGO, FAMILIES OF
VIRGINIA TECH UNIVERSITY
STUDENTS EXPERIENCED A SIMILAR
SHOCK AND SADNESS AS THOSE HERE
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, ARE
EXPERIENCING RIGHT NOW.
SOME OF THEM NOW ARE OFFERING
SOME HELP TO THE PARENTS IN
CONNECTICUT.
CNN'S EMILY SCHMIDT SPOKE WITH A
FATHER WHO LOST HIS DAUGHTER IN
THE SHOOTINGS AT VIRGINIA TECH.
>> Reporter: ONE DAY AFTER
VIRGINIA TECH BECAME HOME TO THE
DEADLIEST SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
U.S. HISTORY, A FATHER SOMEHOW
FOUND THE WORDS TO DESCRIBE THE
UNTHINKABLE.
A DAUGHTER, NOT PICKING UP HER
CELL PHONE.
>> I COULD ONLY ASSUME THE WORST
BECAUSE SHE WAS NOT RESPONDING,
NOBODY KNEW WHO SHE WAS.
>> Reporter: HE TALKED ABOUT HIS
18-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER, THE STAR
STUDENT, THE TEENAGER WHO
THOUGHT DANCE COULD CHANGE THE
WORLD.
WHO WAS SHOT TO DEATH IN FRENCH
CLASS.
AND THAT DAY HE TALKED ABOUT HER
MAINLY IN THE PRESENT TENSE.
>> I KEEP HER IN MY MIND.
HER FACE IS IN MY MENTAL VISION.
AND IT KEEPS ME GOING.
>> Reporter: IT'S BEEN WHAT'S
KEPT HIM GOING FOR MORE THAN
FIVE YEARS.
WHAT IS IT LIKE TALKING ABOUT
HER TODAY?
>> OH, HASN'T CHANGED.
SHE'S IN MY HEART.
>> Reporter: REMEMBERED IN THE
FAMILY PICTURES, ON THE FLAG IN
THE FRONT YARD.
BUT SHE HAS BEEN MISSED AT SO
MUCH.
WHAT WOULD HAVE BEEN HER
GRADUATION.
HER FUNERAL.
HER MEMORIALS.
HER FATHER SAYS NEWTOWN MADE THE
MISSING WORSE ALL OVER AGAIN.
>> THE TRAUMA IS ONLY SKIN DEEP.
SO EVERY TIME SOMETHING LIKE
THIS HAPPENED, YOU OPEN THE
WOUND.
BUT I WILL SAY THAT MY THERAPY,
IS DOING SOMETHING ABOUT IT.
>> Reporter: HE SAID WHEN
VIRGINIA TECH HAPPENED, THERE
WAS NO ONE TO ASK HOW DO YOU GET
THROUGH.
SO HE AND OTHER VICTIM'S
FAMILIES STARTED THE VTV FAMILY
OUTREACH FOUNDATION.
ADVOCATES FOR CAMPUS SAFETY.
TRAINED TO OFFER VICTIM'S
FAMILIES SUPPORT.
>> THEY'RE GOING TO BE ANGRY.
THEY'RE GOING TO BE DEPRESSED.
THEY'RE GOING TO BE SHOCKED.
POSTTRAUMATIC STRESS IS THERE
FOR A LONG, LONG TIME.
BUT THEY'LL HAVE QUESTIONS.
THEIR EXPERIENCE MIGHT BE
PARTICULAR TO THEM.
WE MAY HAVE SOME ANSWERS.
BUT WE ARE THERE TO BE AT THEIR
SERVICE.
THAT'S WHAT WE WERE LOOKING FOR
IN OUR TRAGEDY AT VIRGINIA TECH.
>> Reporter: JOSEPH SOMAHAHA
SAYS THEY WILL ONLY HELP IN
NEWTOWN IF ASKED TO DO SO.
HIS ADVICE, VICTIM'S FAMILIES
SHOULD TAKE CARE OF THEMSELVES
FIRST AND FOCUS ON ISSUES LIKE
GUN CONTROL, SCHOOL SAFETY AND
MENTAL HEALTH LATER.
EMILY SCHMIDT, CNN, WASHINGTON.
>> CERTAINLY REMEMBER SPEAKING
WITH JOSEPH.
HE MADE A DEEP IMPRESSION ON ME
INTERVIEWING HIM IN THE WAKE OF
THAT VIRGINIA TECH UNIVERSITY
TRAGEDY.
OUR HEARTS GO OUT TO HIM AS WELL
AS THE FAMILY MEMBERS OF ALL OF
THOSE KILLED IN THAT TRAGEDY.
HERE IN THE NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, TRAGEDY, ALL THE
VICTIMS OF GUN VIOLENCE ALL
ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
WE'RE SICK AND TIRED OF COVERING
THESE STORIES.
WE'VE COVERED WAY TOO MANY OF
THEM OVER THESE YEARS.
MANY PEOPLE ARE WONDERING, HOW
EASY IS IT FOR SOMEONE TO BUY AN
AUTOMATIC RIFLE LIKE THE ONE THE
SHOOTER USED HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE'RE TAKING A CLOSER LOOK.
MUCH MORE COMING UP.
A SPECIAL EDITION OF "THE
SITUATION ROOM" CONTINUES RIGHT
AFTER THIS.
asty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
>>> UNDERSTANDABLY, THERE'S
CERTAINLY BEEN A LOT OF TALK
ABOUT THE GUNS USED IN THE NEW
TOWN, CONNECTICUT, MASSACRE,
PARTICULARLY THE SEMIAUTOMATIC
ASSAULT-TYPE RIFLE THAT WAS
REPORTEDLY USED IN MOST OF THE
KILLINGS.
SO HOW UNUSUAL IS THIS WEAPON?
HOW EASY IS IT TO GET ONE HERE
IN THE UNITED STATES?
OUR PENTAGON CORRESPONDENT CHRIS
LAWRENCE HAS BEEN LOOKING INTO
THESE QUESTIONS FOR US.
CHRIS, TELL US WHAT YOU CAN
ABOUT THIS EXTREMELY DEADLY
WEAPON.
>> FIRST OF ALL, WOLF, THEY'RE
EVERYWHERE.
I MEAN, YOU CAN LITERALLY BUY
THIS RIFLE AT NEARLY 2,000
WALMART STORES ALL ACROSS THE
COUNTRY.
THERE ARE LITERALLY MILLIONS OF
THESE RIFLES IN HOMES ACROSS
AMERICA.
AND SURPRISINGLY ENOUGH, AFTER
WHAT HAPPENED IN CONNECTICUT,
THAT NUMBER MAY BE GOING UP.
NOT DOWN.
THE AR-15 HAS ALWAYS BEEN A TOP
SELLER AT THIS VIRGINIA GUN
SHOP.
BUT CHUCK SAYS SINCE FRIDAY'S
SHOOTING, SALES HAVE BEEN
SURGING.
>> PEOPLE WANT TO GET THEM
BEFORE THE GOVERNMENT IMPOSES
ANY RESTRICTION AND THEY'RE
BUYING THEM UP IN RECORD NUMBERS
RIGHT NOW.
>> Reporter: WE WEREN'T IN THE
STORE FOR FIVE MINUTES BEFORE
CUSTOMERS STARTED CALLING FOR
GUNS AND AMMO.
>> THOSE MAGAZINES ARE SELLING
FAST.
IN ANTICIPATION OF THE POSSIBLE
BAN ON MAGAZINES.
>> Reporter: HE CAN'T KEEP
ENOUGH OF THE AR-15.
>> WE DO HAVE IN STOCK, IN THE
STORE, THREE OTHER GUNS THAT ARE
OF THE SAME QUALITY AS THE
BUSHMASTER.
>> Reporter: HOW MANY ROUNDS CAN
THIS FIRE PER SECOND?
>> HOW FAST CAN YOU PULL THE
TRIGGER?
>> Reporter: THE AR-15 IS
SEMIAUTOMATIC, MEANING ONE
BULLET PER TRIGGER PULL.
AN AVERAGE CLIP CARRIES 30
ROUNDS.
IT'S A VARIATION OF THE
MILITARY'S M-16.
IT LOOKS TOUGH, OMINOUS.
POLICE SAY ADAM LANZA USED AN
AR-15 IN CONNECTICUT.
IT WAS ALSO USED TO KILL 12
PEOPLE IN A COLORADO MOVIE
THEATER THIS SUMMER.
WHO BUYS THIS WEAPON?
>> EVERYBODY.
>> Reporter: GUNS AND AMMO
MAGAZINE ESTIMATES 1.5 MILLION
HAVE BEEN MADE IN THE LAST FIVE
YEARS ALONE.
DEALERS SAY IT'S THE MOST
POPULAR RIFLE IN AMERICA.
FOR GOOD REASON.
HOW QUICKLY COULD SOMEONE USE
THIS RIFLE --
>> TO SHOOT IT?
VERY LITTLE TRAINING TO SHOOT
IT.
>> Reporter: IT WEIGHS ABOUT
EIGHT POUNDS, TAKES ALL KINDS OF
AMMO AND CAN BE EASILY
CUSTOMIZED WITH VARIOUS LASERS,
STOCKS AND GUN LOCKS.
THE AR-15 IS ACCURATE AND IT HAS
VERY LITTLE KICK.
>> THERE'S LITERALLY NO RECOIL
FROM THIS BECAUSE YOU'RE JUST
SHOOTING A HIGH-POWER .22 ROUND.
ONE OF THE THINGS THAT MAKES IT
VERY CONTROLLABLE.
>> Reporter: A LOT HAS BEEN
TALKING ABOUT THE HEAVY
FIREPOWER OF THE AR-15, BUT
REALLY A LOT OF THE SHOTGUNS AND
RIFLES THAT WE SAW ON THE WALL
THERE ARE MUCH MORE POWERFUL.
THE NORMAL ROUNDS THAT ARE
CHAMBERED IN THIS RIFLE ARE NOT
MUCH MORE OR EVEN LESS THAN A
LOT OF HANDGUNS OUT THERE.
BUT, AGAIN, IT IS EXTREMELY
POPULAR.
THERE ARE MAGAZINES DEDICATED TO
THIS FIREARM, WOLF, AND THAT
SHOWS NO SIGNS OF SLOWING DOWN.
>> CHRIS LAWRENCE, THANKS VERY
MUCH FOR THAT REPORT.
>>> AND WE'RE SAD TO REPORT THIS
JUST COMING INTO THE "SITUATION
ROOM."
SENATOR DANIEL INUWAY OF HAWAII
HAS PASSED AWAY.
A DISTINGUISHED MEMBER OF THE
UNITED STATES SENATE. LONGEST S
THE SENATE.
DISTINGUISHED RECORD AS A
LEGISLATIVE LEADER.
ALSO WAS A WORLD WAR II COMBAT
VETERAN.
HE EARNED THE NATION'S HIGHEST
AWARD FOR MILITARY VALOR AND THE
MEDAL OF VALOR.
SERVED AS CHAIRMAN OF THE IRAN
CONTRA COMMITTEE AND A TERRIFIC
GUY TO ALL OF US WHO COVERED US
OVER THE YEARS.
THEY ARE JOINING US RIGHT NOW
AND VERY SAD NEWS.
HE WAS ILL IN RECENT WEEKS AND
IN THE HOSPITAL.
STILL VERY, VERY SAD THAT
SENATOR INOUYE HAS DIED.
>> NO QUESTION ABOUT IT.
YOU TALKED ABOUT SOME OF THE
MANY, MANY POINTS ON HIS RESUME
THAT MADE HIM SO DISTINGUISHED.
ONE OF THEM IS THAT HE IS
CURRENTLY OR WAS THE LONGEST
SERVING SENATOR HERE.
HE HAS BEEN IN THE SENATE SINCE
1963.
IN FACT, HE HAS REPRESENTED THE
STATE OF HAWAII SINCE IT BECAME
A STATE IN 1959.
HE ALSO WAS CURRENTLY SERVING AS
THE PRESIDENT PROTEM WHICH MADE
HIM 30 IN LINE TO THE
PRESIDENCY.
HE WAS A CONSTANT PRESENCE
AROUND HERE.
HE HAS THE POSITION OF THE
CHAIRMAN OF THE POWERFUL SENATE
APPROPRIATIONS COMMITTEE.
AS YOU SAID, HE REALLY
DISTINGUISHED HIMSELF AS
SOMEBODY WHO IS A VETERAN OF WAR
AND FOUGHT FOR VETERAN'S RIGHTS
AND ONE OF THE FEW REMAINING
PEOPLE TO SERVE AND FOUGHT IN
WORLD WAR II.
NO QUESTION THIS IS A BIG, BIG
LOSS TO THE SENATE.
EVERY SINGLE SENATOR HERE
SERVING HAS SERVED WITH SENATOR
INOUYE BECAUSE HE WAS THE
LONGEST SERVING SENATOR.
>> CHAIRMAN OF THE APPROPRIAT  N
APPROPRIATIONS COMMITTEE AND
DEFENSE APPROPRIATIONS
SUBCOMMITTEE.
HE REALLY WORKED HARD AND WILL
BE MISSED.
OUR DEEPEST CONDOLENCES TO HIS
FAMILY AND HE HAS PASSED AWAY AT
THE AGE OF 88.
THANKS VERY MUCH.
AMONG THOSE MOST DEVASTATED BY
WHAT HAPPENED HERE IN
CONNECTICUT AND NEWTOWN
CONNECTICUT IN THIS TRAGEDY ARE
THE EMERGENCY OFFICIALS AT THAT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE WILL TELL YOU WHAT THEY ARE
NOW SAYING.
hard to see opportuy
in today's challenging
environment.
Unless you have the right
perspective.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
has the vision
and experience to look beyond
the obvious.
We'll uncover opportunities,
find hidden risk,
and make success a reality.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME FOR CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
I HAVE A COLD,
AND I TOOK NYQUIL,
BUT I'M STILL "STUBBED" UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT DOESN'T HAVE A DECONGESTANT.
NO WAY.
[ Male Announcer ] SORRY.
Alka-Seltzer Plus FIGHTS
YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A FAST ACTING
DECONGESTANT
TO RELIEVE YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
[ sighs ] THANKS!
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus.
♪ OH
WHAT A RELIEF IT IS! ♪
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
AND SAVE $1
VISIT Alka-Seltzer ON FACEBOOK.
YOU CAN STAY IN
AND SHARE SOMETHING...
OR YOU CAN GET OUT THERE
AND ACTUALLY SHARE SOMETHING.
♪
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
>>> THIS WAS A VERY PAINFUL
MOMENT FOR A LOT OF US.
WE ARE WALKING OVER TO THE
FIREHOUSE WHERE THE FAMILIES
WERE NOTIFIED THAT THEIR KIDS
HAD BEEN KILLED IN NEWTOWN
FRIDAY MORNING.
THIS WAS SORT OF A COMMAND
CENTER.
TAKE A LOOK OVER HERE AND YOU
CAN SEE WHAT'S GOING ON.
YOU CAN SEE THE LITTLE CHRISTMAS
TREES THAT HAVE BEEN SET UP AND
PEOPLE ARE BRINGING TEDDY BEARS
AND TOYS AND MEMENTOS.
20 OF THESE CHRISTMAS TREES HAVE
BEEN SET UP AND I WILL WALK OVER
AND TAKE A LOOK AT WHAT'S GOING
ON.
LITTLE CANDLES.
PEOPLE ARE PAYING THEIR RESPECTS
TO SOME WONDERFUL KIDS WHO
PASSED AWAY UNFORTUNATE LEEWAY
TOO EARLY.
>> I DON'T KNOW ABOUT YOU, BUT
WHEN I WALK AROUND AND SEE THOSE
LITTLE MEMORIALS THAT HAVE
SPRUNG UP ALL OVER THE PLACE.
>> EVERY DAY THERE MORE PEOPLE
COMING TO GIVE SUPPORT AND BE
PART OF THE COMMUNITY EVEN FROM
OUTSIDE.
YOU WENT TO THAT FIREHOUSE AND
YOU SAW THE MEMORIALS, I SAT IN
ON A SUNDAY CHURCH SERVICE
YESTERDAY AND THE PASTOR THERE
WAS AT THE FIREHOUSE TO FIND OUT
NEWS OF THEIR CHILDREN.
ONE OF THEIR MEMBERS LOST A
CHILD, BENJAMIN WHEELER, IN THE
SHOOTING.
SHE SPOKE SO POWERFULLY AND SO
EMOTIONALLY, BUT WITH SUCH
STRENGTH DURING HER SERVICE.
SHE SAID I'M DONE.
GO.
>> THIS IS HALLOWED GROUND.
THAT'S WHERE EVERYONE GATHERED.
ALL THE FAMILIES DOWN THE
STREET.
THEY STAYED THERE.
ANOTHER EXAMPLE I LEARNED
DRIVING AROUND IN AREAS.
THIS IS A FIRST RESPONDER HERE
WITHIN 20 MINUTES AND HAS A
GRANDCHILD AT SANDY HOOK AND HIS
WIFE IS A SCHOOL BUS DRIVER FOR
THE SCHOOL SYSTEM.
EVERYONE IS IMPACTED.
EVERYONE.
>> IT'S TRUE.
DURING HIS VERY, VERY POWERFUL
SPEECH LAST NIGHT AT THIS
MEMORIAL, THE PRESIDENT READ THE
NAMES OF THE DEAD ONE BY ONE
SAYING GOD HAS CALLED THEM ALL
HOME.
WE HAVE TAKEN HIS WORDS OUT OF
THE PICTURES HE NAMED.
>> LET THE LITTLE CHILDREN COME
TO ME, JESUS SAID.
DO NOT HINDER THEM.
FOR TO SUCH BELONGS THE KIMDOM
OF HEAVEN.
CHARLOTTE, DANIEL, OLIVIA,
JOSEPHINE, ANA, DYLAN,
MADELEINE, CATHERINE, CHASE,
JESSE, JAMES, GRACE, EMILIE,
JACK, NOAH, CAROLINE, JESSICA,
BENJAMIN, AVIELLE, ALLISON.
GOD HAS CALL THEM ALL HOME.
FOR THOSE OF US WHO REMAIN, LET
US FIND THE STRENGTH TO CARRY ON
AND MAKE OUR COUNTRY WORTHY OF
THEIR MEMORY.
.
>> HEARTBROKEN FAMILIES CLING TO
ONE ANOTHER.
SURVIVORS SAY GOODBYE.
THE FIRST YOUNG VICTIMS OF THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL MASSACRE ARE
BURIED AND THE GRIEF IS
OVERWHELMING.
>> IT'S EVERYTHING YOU CAN
IMAGINE PLUS SOME.
IT'S WORSE.
>> I'M WOLF BLITZER IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THE STATE'S GOVERNOR SAID THERE
NO WORDS TO DESCRIBE THE PAIN OF
PARENTS BURYING THEIR CHILDREN
LET ALONE CHILDREN KILLED IN
SUCH A HORRIFIC ACT OF VIOLENCE.
6-YEAR-OLDS JACK PINTO AND NOAH
POSNER ARE THE FIRST VICTIMS OF
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SHOOTING
TO BE LAID TO REST.
THERE WILL BE TWO DOZEN MORE
BURIALS JUST AS GUT WRENCHING AS
THE ONES HERE TODAY.
POLICE ARE LEARNING MORE ABOUT
THE GUNMAN, ADAM LNZA.
THEY ARE FOLLOWING THE LATEST ON
THE INVESTIGATION FOR US.
WHAT ARE YOU LEARNING?
>> WE CAN TELL YOU WITHIN THE
LAST HALF HOUR, FOUR UNMARKED
POLICE CARS WITH DETECTIVES
PULLED OUT OF THE LANZA HOME.
THERE HAVE BEEN LIGHTS ON IN THE
GROUND FLOOR IN THE CORNER ROOM.
THOSE LIGHTS OFF THE SHADES
DRAWN ACROSS THE HOME IN THIS
PARTICULAR AREA.
WE HAVE PASSED A COUPLE OF HOMES
THAT HAVE SQUAD CARS IN FRONT OF
THEM.
PATROL CARS IN FRONT OF THEM.
WE BELIEVE THOSE ARE HOMES THAT
SOME OF THE VICTIMS HAD.
LANZA'S HOME IS A CRIME SCENE.
THEY WERE ABLE TO RECOVER PIECES
OF A SMASHED COMPUTER.
THAT COMPUTER NOW BEING ANALYZED
BY LAW ENFORCEMENT FOLKS WHO ARE
ABLE TO RETRIEVE A LOT OF DATA.
THEY ARE LOOKING AT E-MAILS AND
WANT TO KNOW WHAT WEBSITES HE
VISIT AND WHO HE MAY HAVE COME
INTO CONTACT WITH AND WHY HE MAY
HAVE CHOSEN THIS SCHOOL TO CARRY
OUT THE MASSACRE.
THE DETAILS ARE SKETCHY, BUT
STARTING TO COME TOGETHER.
>> ADAM LANZA MOVED INTO THIS
HOUSE WHEN HE WAS ABOUT 6 YEARS
OLD, THE SAME AGE AS THE FIRST
GRADERS HE IS ACCUSED OF
KILLING.
HE DID NOT GO TO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY, BUT A WOMAN SAID HER
CHILD AND ADAM LANZA HAD BEEN
CLASSMATES THERE IN THE FIRST
AND THIRD GREATS.
POLICE ARE SEARCHING FOR A
CONNECTION AS TO WHY HE CHOSE TO
CARRY OUT THE MASSACRE THERE
LAST WEEK.
LITTLE IS KNOWN ABOUT ADAM
LANZA, BUT AS A FRESHMAN IN
2007, LANZA SEEMED SO
VULNERABLE.
THE FORMER SCHOOL SECURITY
DIRECTOR TOLD CNN HE WARNED HIS
SCHOOL OFFICERS TO KEEP AN EYE
ON THE CHILD SO HE WOULD NOT BE
PICKED ON OR BULLIED.
LANZA WAS ASSIGNED TO SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGISTS AS THE SECURITY
DIRECTOR.
THOUGH LANZA JOINED THE TECH
CLUB, HE REMAINED WITH DRAWN.
AT AGE 16, LANZ ENROLLED AS A
STUDENT AT WESTERN CONNECTICUT
STATE UNIVERSITY ABOUT 15
MINUTES FROM HIS HOME, TAKING
AMONG OTHER CLASSES, GERMAN,
COMPUTER SCIENCE, AMERICAN
HISTORY AND MACRO ECONOMICS.
HE DROPPED OUT IN 2009 AND DID
NOT RETURN.
HIS HIGH SCHOOL FRIEND RAN INTO
NANCY LANZA AND HE SAID THE MOM
SAID HE WAS DOING REALLY WELL IN
COLLEGE.
SHE TOLD HIM SHE TAKEN HIM
SHOOTING AS A HOBBY AND LIKED TO
GO TO THE GUN RANGE.
>> IT'S UNCLEAR WHETHER SHE WAS
CONTINUING HIS EDUCATION, BUT
CNN LEARNED HIS MOTHER CONFIDED
TO A FRIEND THIS WAS LIKELY HER
LAST WINTER HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
SHE WANTED TO GO SOMEWHERE WHERE
HE COULD GO TO COLLEGE.
SHE WAS LOOKING TO GO ACROSS
COUNTRY TO WASHINGTON STATE,
POSSIBLY PUTTING HIM IN COURSES
THERE.
HE IS DESCRIBED AS A GENIUS,
INCREDIBLY SMART AND SOME OF HIS
FRIENDS WHO TALK ABOUT HIM SAY
WHILE HE WAS VERY, VERY QUIET
AND SHY, ONCE YOU GOT HIM TO
OPEN UP HE SEEMED TO JOKE.
HE ENJOYED BEING IN THAT
COMPANY.
EXTREMELY WITH DRAWN.
INVESTIGATORS HOPE THEY CAN
PIECE TOGETHER THE INVESTIGATION
ON THAT COMPUTER.
THEY DESCRIBED IT AS SEIZING
VERY GOOD EVIDENCE.
WHAT THAT EVIDENCE IS, WHEN
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE ARE
READY TO RELEASE IT, THEY WILL
HOLD A PRESS CONFERENCE.
WOLF?
>> THANKS VERY MUCH FOR THAT.
SCHOOLS HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT WILL REOPEN EXCEPT
FOR THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AND FOR GOOD REASON.
>> FOR GOOD REASON, BUT THEY ARE
LOOKING FOR A TEMPORARY
MAKESHIFT SCHOOL.
I SPOKE WITH OFFICIALS ABOUT HOW
THEY WILL MAKE THAT HAPPEN.
AFTER THE HORROR OF FRIDAY, NO
ONE WANTS TO SEND THE CHILDREN
BACK TO SANDY HOOK AND AT THE
SAME TIME THEY ARE SEARCHING FOR
A SENSE OF NORMALCY FOR THE
CHILDREN.
THAT WHEN IT COMES TO SCHOOL,
THAT IS WHEN THE NORTH OF MONROE
STEPPED IN.
DESKS TO BULLETIN BORES HEADING
HERE TO THE NEIGHBORING TOWN OF
MONROE.
>> BOOK CASES.
>> THAT'S THE STUDENT MATERIALS
AND THE BACKPACKS THEY LEFT.
THEY WALKED INTO A CLASSROOM AS
CLOSE AS POSSIBLE AS THEIR
CLASSROOM THEY LEFT.
>> STEVE IS THE TOWN'S CHIEF
EXECUTIVE AND AS SOON AS HE
HEARD ABOUT THE HORROR HE
OFFERED UP CHALK HIM MIDDLE
SCHOOL WHICH IS EMPTY BECAUSE IT
CLOSED RECENTLY.
THEY MET WITH THE TEACHERS AND
STUDENTS AT SUNDAY'S VIGIL.
>> MOST WERE VERY, VERY THANKFUL
THEY HAD A PLACE TO GO BACK TO
WORK.
THE CHILDREN AND TEACHERS WHO
WERE -- IT WAS EMOTIONAL.
>> ALL DAY CONTRACTORS DONATED
THEIR TIME TO TRANSFORM THIS
FORMER MIDDLE SCHOOL INTO AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> JUST TO GIVE YOU A SENSE, THE
TOILET ALL HAVE TO BE REPLACED
TO A SMALLER SIZE.
THINGS HAVE TO BE MADE
ACCESSIBLE.
TOWEL DISPENSERS LOWERED.
>> JIM AUGUSTINE IS THE
SUPERINTENDENT.
>> WHY IS IT SO IMPORTANT TO GET
THE STUDENTS INTO A BUILDING
LIKE CHALK HILL AND BACK IN THE
CLASSROOM?
>> THAT'S EXACTLY THE SENSE OF
NORMALCY THAT THEY NEED TO BEGIN
THE HEALING PROCESS AND FEEL
SAVE AND PROTECT AND GET BACK
INTO A ROUTINE.
>> ONE CHANGE EVERY PARENT WILL
NOTICE AT SCHOOLS ACROSS THE
AREA AFTER SANDY HOOK POLICE
PATROL.
>> SORRY THAT A PROTECTIVE IN
ISSUE AND THE NEW NORMAL OR IS
THAT MORE A WAY TO HELP FAMILIES
AND STUDENTS ALLEVIATE ANXIETY
AS THEY RETURN TO CLASS?
>> ALL OF THE ABOVE.
UNFORTUNATELY IT MAY BE THE NEW
NORMAL AND THE WAY WE NEED TO
TAKE ACTION IN THE FUTURE.
>> THERE IS NO OFFICIAL DATE FOR
THE STUDENTS TO START AT CHALK
HILL MIDDLE SCHOOL.
IT WILL BE AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
OFFICIALS SAY THE BUILDING
ITSELF, ALL THE UPGRADES AND
TECHNOLOGY AND EVERYTHING THAT
NEEDS TO BE DONE AS WELL AS
INSPECTIONS AND THE FIRE
MARSHALL COULD BE DONE AS EARLY
AS TOMORROW WHICH IS AMAZING
WHEN YOU THINK OF WHAT A MASSIVE
UNDERTAKING IT IS TO PULL THIS
OFF.
IT WILL BE UP TO NEWTOWN SCHOOL
OFFICIALS.
THEY WANT TO BRING THE CHILDREN
BACK IN.
THE GOVERNOR SIGNED AN EXECUTIVE
ORDER TO CUT THROUGH THE RED
TAPE TO ELIMINATE ANY HURDLES
THEY NEEDED TO JUMP OVER TO MAKE
IT HAPPEN SO THEY COULD TRANSFER
OVER EASILY.
>> I HAVE BEEN HERE SINCE FRIDAY
NIGHT AND KATE HAS BEEN HERE
SINCE FRIDAY NIGHT AS WELL.
WE HAVE SEEN SO MUCH PAIN AND
ALSO SEEN A LOT OF STRENGTH.
>> WHERE YOU SHOULD SEE HOLIDAY
DECORATIONS, WE ARE SEEING
MEMORIALS IN HONOR OF THE
MASSACRE VICTIMS.
YOU HAVE BEEN DOING GREAT WORK
AND TRAVELING AROUND TOWN
TALKING TO FOLKS.
WHAT ARE YOU HEARING?
>> THIS IS THE LARGEST PUBLIC
MEMORIAL HERE IN THE HEART OF
NEWTOWN.
THIS STARTED OUT WITH CANDLES
FOR THE VICTIMS.
YOU MAY HEAR MUSIC IN THE
BACKGROUND.
THAT SAY COLLEGE GROUP WHO DROVE
UP FROM FLORIDA AND SINGING AND
PLAYING MUSIC.
YOU SEE EVERYTHING FROM TEDDY
BEARS TO FLOWERS AND LEGOS.
YOU MIGHT SEE THE WHITE
ORNAMENTS.
THIS IS FROM A COUPLE -- THEIR
WEDDING GIFT FROM JAPAN.
THEY BROUGHT THIS AND HUNG IT
HERE.
JUST ABOUT EVERYWHERE YOU GO,
YOU ARE SEEING THESE MAKESHIFT
MEMORIALS.
>> ANGELS LINE ONE ROADWAY IN
REMEMBRANCE OF EACH VICTIM.
ALONG THE HIGHWAY, FLAGS FLY IN
THEIR HONOR.
THERE SIGNS OF SUPPORT
EVERYWHERE.
THIS KWAQUAINT TOWN SYMBOLIZES
NIGHTMARE.
FOR THE LOCAL PAPER, BEFORE LAST
FRIDAY THE BIG RECENT HEADLINE
WAS A VANDALIZED CEMETERY.
NOW THRUST INTO A WORLDWIDE
SPOTLIGHT, THE NORMALLY QUIET
MAIN STREET IS PACKED WITH MEDIA
AND OUTSIDERS.
THAT'S WHY KEVIN TRIED TO DO
SOMETHING AWAY FROM THE CROWDS
IN TOWN.
HE HUNG A HUGE FLAG.
>> MY SON SERVED IN AFGHAN
STWHAN WE CAME HOME.
WE HAD ONE OF THE FLAGS.
WE HAVE THE MEANS TO FLY IT AT
CERTAIN OCCASIONS FOR MY SON.
>> UNDER THIS FLAG, A MAKESHIFT
MEMORIAL GREW.
>> WE CAME HERE AROUND 11:00 AND
SET THE FLAG UP FOR THE PEOPLE
OF NEWTOWN.
PEOPLE STARTED DROPPING OFF
TEDDY BEARS AND GIVES AND
FLOWERS FOR THE FAMILIES.
DONATIONS FOR THE FUNERALS.
WE HAVE BEEN DROPPING THE MONEY
OFF TO THE CHURCH.
IT KEEPS GROWING.
>> AT THE NEARBY BLUE COLONY
DINER, BLACK MOURNING RIBBONS
ARE HUNG AROUND.
THE DINER IS A SPOT WHERE PEOPLE
ARE COMING FOR COMFORT OVER
FOOD.
>> IT'S A MEETING PLACE FOR
GRIEVING FAMILIES AND FRIENDS
AND RELATIVES AND EVEN
PASSERBIES HAVE BEEN COMING IN
AND SHARING AND SORROW.
>> THE DINER MANAGER WE SPOKE
WITH SAID HE HAS BEEN GETTING
CALLS FROM ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
PEOPLE CALLING AND SAYING THEY
WANT TO PAY FOR MEALS FOR
FAMILIES OF VICTIMS.
HE OFTEN JUST PICKS UP THE PHONE
AND THERE IS CRYING ON THE OTHER
END OF THE LINE.
WE FOUND A TOY STORE, THE ONLY
TOY STORE AND THE OWNER SAID SHE
HAS GOTTEN CALLS FROM PEOPLE
AROUND THE COUNTRY WANTING TO
MAKE DONATIONS.
IT'S BEEN REALLY SURPRISED BY
THE OUT POURING AND TOUCHED BY
THE OUT POURING FROM PEOPLE
AROUND THE COUNTRY.
>> THESE EMOTIONS ARE SO RAW
RIGHT NOW.
THANKS FOR THAT.
SANJAY GUPTA IS JOINING US.
YOU HAVE BEEN OUT AND WORKING ON
SOMETHING VERY SPECIAL THAT YOU
ARE GOING TO BE SHARING WITH OUR
VIEWERS LATER THIS HOUR.
>> WE TEND TO LOOK AT A LOT OF
THESE PREVIOUS TRAGEDIES IN
HINDSIGHT.
THE QUESTION A LOT OF PEOPLE
HAVE, CLUES THAT PEOPLE CAN DO
PROACTIVELY OR RECOGNIZE THAT IS
TOUGH AS YOU MIGHT IMAGINE.
IF YOU LOOK THROUGHOUT THE
HISTORY, WHAT CHARACTERIZES SOME
OF THESE PEOPLE THAT HAVE BEEN
INVOLVED WITH THE TRAGEDIES.
THAT'S WHAT WE DECIDED TO FOCUS
ON.
THESE ARE SPECIFIC THINGS.
>> YOU HAVE SOME COMMON THREADS?
>> COMMON THREADS.
AGAIN THERE OBVIOUSLY NO RULE
WHEN IS IT COMES TO THAT SORT OF
STUFF.
DESPITE WHAT THEY HAVE BEEN
TALKING B THESE ARE FEW AND FAR
BETWEEN WHEN IT COMES TO THE
NUMBERS.
A FEW PEOPLE ARE EXPERTS AND
THEY TALK ABOUT THE FACT THAT IF
PEOPLE HARDLY EVER SNAP.
THAT'S COME UP QUITE A BIT.
YOU HAVE TO KNOW SPECIFICALLY
WHERE TO LOOK AND THE PATTERNS.
THAT'S WHAT WE HAVE BEEN FOLK E
USING O.
>> IF THERE IS MORE RESEARCH,
MAYBE THEY CAN PREVENT THE
TRAGEDIES.
>> EXACTLY.
>> THIS IS IN THE CONTEXT THAT
IS UNDER RESOURCED AND DIFFICULT
TO GET PEOPLE INTO.
ONE THING HA IS INTERESTING AND
WE WILL TALK ABOUT IS THE IDEA
OF MEDICATIONS.
WHEN YOU GIVE MEDICATIONS, THERE
VULNERABLE TIMES WHEN YOU ARE
STARTING AND TAKING A PATIENT
OFF THE MEDICATION.
THESE ARE TIMES WHEN YOU CAN
INDUCE PSYCHOSIS.
LOSS OF TOUCH WITH REALITY.
DECREASED JUDGMENT AND
IMPULSIVITY.
PEOPLE NEED TO BE MONITORED.
THIS IS NOT CASTING BLAME, BUT
WHEN WE LOOK AT THE MONITORS.
>> WHY DO YOU THINK WHEN WE LOOK
AT THE THINGS IN HINDSIGHT THAT
IS RIGHT AND DO YOU THINK --
WHERE DO YOU THINK THE MAJOR
ISSUE IS IN TERMS OF DIAGNOSING
MENTAL ILLNESS AND GETTING
PEOPLE IN TO THE MENTAL HEALTH
SYSTEM.
WE ALWAYS TALK ABOUT THIS AFTER
EVERY TRAGEDY.
>> FOR ALWAYS SEEMS LIKE WE TALK
ABOUT THIS.
ONE THING I HAVE LEARNED THAT
MAY BE SURPRISING, PEOPLE SEEM
TO THINK THE SIGNS WERE IGNORED.
THAT'S HARDLY EVER THE CASE
ACTUALLY.
FAMILIES DO RECOGNIZE THE SIGNS
AND LOVED ONES AND NEIGHBORS.
AND THEY ANGUISH OVER IT.
THE PROBLEM IS THE NEXT STEP.
THE THRESHOLD FOR GETTING PEOPLE
IN IS USUALLY IF THEY HAVE
IMMINENT HARM TO THEMSELVES OR
OTHERS.
THAT'S THE THRESHOLD AND LIKE
HAVING A HEARD ATTACK.
THAT'S TOO LATE AS YOU KNOW.
YOU HAVE TO TREAT THE PEOPLE
EARLIER.
IT'S NOT SO MUCH THE SIGNS THAT
ARE BEING RECOGNIZED, BUT THE
SYSTEM HAS FAILED.
YOU HEARD THE PRESIDENT SAY
MENTAL HEALTH.
>> THEY DECREASE THE STIGMA
WHICH IS VERY IMPORTANT.
>> THE FULL REPORT LATER THIS
HOUR.
EMERGENCY OFFICIALS HERE IN
NEWTOWN ARE PAYING TRIBUTE TO
THE VICTIMS OF THE SCHOOL
MASSACRE.
CHILDREN DESPERATELY HOPE TO
SAVE AND THEY COULDN'T.
WE WILL HEAR FROM A FIREFIGHTER.
>> ALSO WILL PRESIDENT OBAMA
LIVE UP TO HIS PROMISE TO THE
PEOPLE OF NEW AND THE NATION TO
TRY TO PREVENT FUTURE SHOOTING
TRAGEDIES.
>>> AS THE FIRST YOUNG VICTIMS
ARE BURIED HERE IN CONNECTICUT,
THE CRIES ARE GROWING LOUDER FOR
NEW FEDERAL GUN CONTROL
MEASURES.
SOME BELIEVE IT COULD BE A
TURNING POINT IN THE GUN DEBATE
IN AMERICA IF THE PRESIDENT OF
THE UNITED STATES FOLLOWS
THROUGH ON HIS CALL TO ACTION.
LET'S GO TO THE WHITE HOUSE.
BRIANNA KEILAR HAS THE LATEST.
>> I'M NOT SURE IF YOU NOTICED,
BUT PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS NOT EVEN
UTTERED THE WORD GUN SINCE THE
SHOOTING ON FRIDAY.
GUN RIGHTS ADVOCATES HAVE STAYED
OUT OF THIS DEBATE, BUT GUN
CONTROL ADVOCATES HAVE NOT.
THE PRESIDENT IS MISSING AN
OPPORTUNITY TO OUTLINE SPECIFIC
GUN CONTROL MEASURES BECAUSE
THEY SAY PUBLIC INTEREST IN THIS
IS HIGH ON AN ISSUE THAT HAS NOT
BEEN A PRIORITY FOR PRESIDENT
OBAMA OR CONGRESS IN RECENT
YEARS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA PROMISED SUNDAY
IN NEWTOWN TO TAKE ACTION.
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS I WILL
USE WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE
HOLDS TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW
CITIZENS FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT TO
MENTAL HEALTH PROFESSIONALS TO
PARENTS AND EDUCATORS IN AN
EFFORT AIMED AT PREVENTING MORE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS.
>> HERE GAVE NO SPECIFICS.
DIANNE FEINSTEIN WANTS TO BAN
SEMI AUTOMATIC WEAPONS.
>> HE IS GOING TO HAVE A BILL TO
LEAD ON BECAUSE AS A FIRST DAY
BILL, I WILL INTRODUCE IN THE
SENATE AND THE SAME BILL WILL BE
INTRODUCED IN THE HOUSE, A BILL
TO BAN ASSAULT WEAPONS.
>> FAR FROM FAKE TAKING THE LET,
THEY WON'T SEE IF THE WHITE
HOUSE WILL SUPPORT THE BILL.
JAY KARN CARNEY DID NOT SUPPORT
MEASURE.
THAT IRKS A NUMBER OF DEMOCRATS
CHO WHO SUPPORT GUN CONTROL
INCLUDING CONGRESSWOMAN CAROLYN
CARTHY WHOSE HUSBAND DIED AND
SON WAS INJURIED ON A LONG
ISLAND TRAIN IN 1993.
>> WHEN THE WHITE HOUSE, CARNEY
CAME OUT AND SAID THIS WAS NOT A
TIME TO TALK ABOUT GUN VIOLENCE
AND LEGISLATION.
I CALLED THE WHITE HOUSE AND IT
WAS LIKE WHAT ARE YOU TALKING
ABOUT?
WE SHOULD HAVE BEEN TALKING
ABOUT THIS YEARS AGO.
>> McCARTHY AND OTHERS INCLUDING
NEW YORK MAYOR MICHAEL BLOOMBERG
SAID NOW IS THE TIME TO ACT
WHILE THE AMERICAN PUBLIC IS
PAYING ATTENTION TO THIS
TRAGEDY.
AFTER PAST SHOOTINGS, CONGRESS'S
APPETITE TO ACT ON GUN VIOLENCE
WANED QUICKLY.
>> INNOCENT IT MORE LIKELY THAT
PEOPLE PRERE TREAT TO THEIR
CORNERS WHICH YOU DON'T WANT TO
SEE FURTHER OUT FROM THE EVENT.
>> IT IS HARD TO THINK ABOUT 20
6 AND 7-YEAR-OLDS AND WHAT
HAPPENED TO THEM ON FRIDAY AND
IMAGINE IN A FEW WEEKS OR A FEW
MONTHS THAT PAIN WOULD NOT STILL
BE INCREDIBLY INTENSE AND
PRESENT.
>> POLLS SHOW THAT AMERICANS'S
ATTITUDES TOWARDS RESTRICTIONS
ON GUNS HAVEN'T WAIVERED WITH
OTHER SHOOTINGS.
ARIZONA, COLORADO AND WISCONSIN.
A NEW POLL OUT IN "WASHINGTON
POST" POLL SHOWS THAT THE PUBLIC
IS SPENDING TO THIS SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT DIFFERENTLY.
44% OF THOSE POLED STRONGLY
SUPPORT STRICTER GUN WELL LAWS
UP FROM 39% IN AUGUST AND 5%
FEWER ARE STRONGLY OPPOSED.
THE QUESTION IS WILL THAT BE
ENOUGH AND WILL IT LAST AND WILL
IT GIVE FUEL TO GUN CONTROL
ADVOCATES.
>> BRIANNA, THANKS VERY MUCH.
LISTENING TO THE PRESIDENT AND
WATCHING HIM GET EMOTIONAL, I
THINK HE IS GOING TO TRY.
I DON'T KNOW IF HE WILL SUCCEED,
BUT I KNOW HE WILL TRY IN THIS
SECOND TERM TO DO SOMETHING
ABOUT GUN CONTROL.
>> HE LEFT THE IMPRESSION THAT
WAS HIS GOAL AND ONE OF HIS
FOCUSES.
>> A LOT OF OTHER STUFF.
HE'S GOING TO TRY.
>> THIS IS QUICKLY BECOMING A
PRIORITY.
>> STILL AHEAD, PEOPLE FROM
ACROSS THE NATION ARE SENDING
GIFTS FOR THE MAKESHIFT
MEMORIALS.
SO MANY MEMORIALS CONTINUE TO
POP UP.
CNN'S BROOKE BALDWIN CAUGHT UP
WITH A RESPONDER DELIVERING
CHRISTMAS WREATHS FROM OREGON
AND HAS QUITE A STORY TO TELL.
I ALWAYS WAIT
UNTIL THE LAST MINUTE.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME FOR CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a
Droid Incredible 4G LTE
by HTC for $49.99.
♪
MANY HOT DOGS
ARE WITHIN YOU.
TRY PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO,
IT'S THE POWER OF PEPTO,
BUT IT FITS IN YOUR POCKET.
NOW TELL THE WORLD
DANIEL...
OF PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO.
>> PER WE WANT TO CONTINUE
HONORING THE VICTIMS OF THIS
TRAGEDY.
JOSEPHINE GAY LIKED RIDING A
BIKE AND SELLING LEMONADE.
HER FAVORITE COLOR WAS PURPLE.
CATHERINE HUBBARD IS REMEMBERED
FOR BRIGHT RED HAIR, CONSTANT
SMILE AND LOVE OF SPORTS AND
COMPASSION FOR ANIMALS.
CHARLOTTE BACON WAS SWEET,
OUTGOING WITH A MASS OF
BEAUTIFUL RED CURLS.
SHE LOVED SCHOOL AND LOVED
DRESSES.
SO ADORABLE AND SO SAD.
NOR GLIMPSES OF YOUNGSTERS WITH
SO MUCH PROMISE GUNNED DOWN AND
GONE FOREVER.
>> EVERYONE HERE IS DEVASTATED.
EVERYONE INCLUDING THE EMERGENCY
OFFICIALS AND THEY WERE THE
FIRST TO ARRIVE ON THE SCENE.
BROOKE BALDWIN IS BACK WITH US
AND YOU CAME BACK FROM A MOVING
CONVERSATION.
>> WE JUST TALKED TO TWO
VOLUNTEER FIREFIGHTERS WITH THE
NEWTOWN HOOK AND LADDER AND THEY
WERE TALKING TO US ABOUT
FIREFIGHTERS.
THEY TRIED TO USE HUMOR TO
DIFFUSE THE SITUATIONS.
THEY WERE TALKING ABOUT THE
TRUCKFULS OF TEDDY BEARS FROM
PEOPLE ACROSS THE COUNTRY THAT
THEY HAVE BEEN ABLE TO
DISTRIBUTE TO THE KIDS TO PUT
SMILES ON FACES IN A TRYING
TIME.
I RAN ACROSS ANOTHER FIREFIGHTER
TODAY IN THE MIDST OF MANY
REEVES.
I SAW THEM UNPACKING WREATH
AFTER WREATH.
HE SAID SOMEONE IN PORTLAND,
OREGON.
TAKE A LOOK.
>> HOW MANY ARE THERE?
>> THEY WERE SENT TO THE
FIREHOUSE THROUGH U.P.S.
>> DID YOU KNOW THEY WERE
COMING?
>> NO.
THEY WERE -- THE TRUCK PULLED UP
AND SHE SAID I AM DELIVERING 26
WREATHS AND WE FIGURED WE WOULD
COME UP WITH A PLACE TO PUT
THEM.
TRYING TO KEEP THEM TOGETHER.
SHIPPED FROM OREGON.
>> HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN HERE?
>> SINCE FRIDAY.
>> WHERE ARE YOU BASED OUT OF?
>> SANDY HOOK.
>> HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN HERE.
>> WE ARE GOING HOME TO SLEEP.
>> SINCE HIGH SCHOOL.
I'M 38.
>> DID YOU EVER IN A MILLION
YEARS THINK YOU WOULD BE
EXPERIENCING THIS IN YOUR LITTLE
TOWN?
>> NOBODY THOUGHT THAT.
>> WHERE WERE YOU WHEN YOU
HEARD?
>> WORKING.
I WORK ACROSS TOWN.
WE SAW THE HELICOPTERS.
>> WHEN YOU SAW THE HELICOPTERS,
WHAT DID YOU THINK WAS IT WAS?
>> NOT ON THE SCALE IT WAS.
ONE OR TWO.
WE HEARD IT WAS THE PRINCIPAL
AND AS TIME WENT ON WE GOT THE
REPORTS AND DIDN'T BELIEVE IT.
WE CAME DOWN THE ROAD AND IT WAS
ALL SURREAL.
SEEING ALL THE CARS AND ALL
THIS.
IT'S TOUGH.
>> WHERE DID YOU GO ONCE YOU SAW
THE CAR?
>> STRAIGHT TO THE FIREHOUSE AND
FROM THERE WE JUST HAVEN'T LEFT.
>> HELP US AROUND THE WORLD
UNDERSTAND WHAT YOU AS A FIRST
RESPONDER ARE GOING THROUGH.
>> SADNESS.
ANGER.
GUILT IN SOME ASPECTS.
>> WHY GUILT?
WHAT COULD YOU HAVE DONE?
>> EXACTLY.
WE WERE HAVING COUNSELING SO AS
A GROUP.
>> WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF THE
WREATHS?
JUST PEOPLE YOU DON'T KNOW
SENDING YOU ALL THESE WREATHS TO
PUT UP IN YOUR TOWN.
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY TO THE PEOPLE
IN PORTLAND, OREGON?
>> THANK YOU.
IT MAKES US FEEL WARM TO KNOW
THIS IS AMAZING THAT PEOPLE THAT
FAR AWAY CARE ABOUT US.
.
>> IN THIS CONVERSATION I HAD
WITH THE TWO OTHER FIREFIGHTERS,
JUST THIS LAST HOUR, I SAID WHAT
WILL NEWTOWN LOOK LIKE IN A
MONTH.
ONCE WE ARE GONE AND THE QUIET
RETURNS, HE SAID SCARRED.
HE SAID WE WILL NEVER BE THE
SAME.
THAT TOWN YOU HAVE TO EXPLAIN
THAT IS JUST NEAR DANBURY SORT
OF NEAR HARDFORD.
YOU SAY NEWTOWN AND PEOPLE KNOW
EXACTLY WHERE IT IS.
THEY'LL MOVE ON, BUT IT'S THE
IMAGES OF THE PARENTS AT THE
FIREHOUSE AND SOME OF THEM
RETRIEVING THEIR KIDS AND THE
PARENTS LEFT WITHOUT THE
CHILDREN.
I SAW TEARS IN EYES AND THAT'S
THE IMAGE THAT THEY WILL NEVER
FORGET.
>> YOU NOTICED IT WHILE WE
TALKED ABOUT IT, THING I KNOW I
WILL TAKE AWAY WHEN WE GO AND
WHEN WE LEAVE IS THE SENSE OF
COMMUNITY OF HOW PEOPLE HAVE
JUST COME TOGETHER.
ONE PERSON SAID I KNOW WE WILL
BE REMEMBERED AS NEWTOWN WHERE
THIS MASSACRE HAPPENED, BUT I
ALSO WANT TO BE REMEMBERED AS A
TOWN WHERE THE COMMUNITY FOUGHT
BACK.
FOUGHT TO BE REMEMBERED FOR
SOMETHING OTHER THAN THIS
TRAGEDY.
>> NOT JUST BEAM WITHIN THE
TOWN, BUT AROUND CONNECTICUT.
GOVERNOR MALLOY BROKE DOWN INTO
TEARS AND REACHING OUT TO THE
TOWN.
>> A LOT OF STRENGTH THOUGH.
>> YOU ARE GETTING EMOTIONAL.
>> WE ALL ARE.
>> UNDERSTANDABLY SO.
GOOD REPORT.
THANK YOU.
>> THERE HAVE BEEN MANY
BREAKTHROUGHS IN MEDICAL
SCIENCE.
WHAT HAVE WE LEARNED ABOUT WHAT
GOES ON INSIDE THE MINDS OF
SERIAL KILLERS?
SANJAY GUPTA WHO IS A
NEUROSURGEON HAS A NEW REPORT.
YOU WANT TO SEE THIS.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
HEY, LOOK!
A SHOOTING STAR!
MAKE A WISH!
I WISH WE COULD
LIE HERE FOREVER.
I WISH THIS TEST DRIVE WAS OVER,
SO WE COULD HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
TEST DRIVE!
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A JETTA.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN,
$0 DUE AT SIGNING, $0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
AWW MAN.
[ Male Announcer ] RETURNS
ARE EASY WITH FREE PICKUP
FROM THE U.S. POSTAL SERVICE.
WE'LL EVEN DROP OFF BOXES
IF YOU NEED THEM.
VISIT USPS.COM
PAY, PRINT,
AND HAVE IT PICKED UP FOR FREE.
ANY TIME OF YEAR.
♪
NICE SWEATER.
THANK YOU.
♪
YOU'LL ALSO CARE ABOUT
OUR NEW OFFER.
YOU GET ACCESS TO NURSES WHO
CAN HELP WITH YOUR QUESTIONS.
AND YOUR LOVED ONE CAN GET
EXELON PATCH FREE FOR 30 DAYS.
IF THE DOCTOR FEELS
IT'S RIGHT FOR THEM.
IT CANNOT CHANGE
HOW THE DISEASE PROGRESSES.
HOSPITALIZATION
AND RARELY DEATH
HAVE BEEN REPORTED IN PATIENTS
WHO WORE MORE THAN ONE PATCH
AT A TIME.
THE MOST COMMON SIDE EFFECTS
OF EXELON PATCH
ARE NAUSEA, VOMITING,
AND DIARRHEA.
THE LIKELIHOOD AND SEVERITY
OF THESE SIDE EFFECTS
MAY INCREASE
AS THE DOSE INCREASES.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
LOSS OF APPETITE OR WEIGHT.
PATIENTS WHO WEIGH
LESS THAN 110 POUNDS
MAY EXPERIENCE
MORE SIDE EFFECTS.
PEOPLE AT RISK
FOR STOMACH ULCERS
WHO TAKE CERTAIN
OTHER MEDICINES
SHOULD TALK TO THEIR DOCTOR
BECAUSE SERIOUS
STOMACH PROBLEMS
SUCH AS BLEEDING MAY WORSEN.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
SLOW HEART RATE.
THIRTY DAYS OF EXELON PATCH
FREE FOR YOUR LOVED ONE.
ACCESS TO TRAINED NURSES
FOR YOU.
CALL 1-855-999-1399
OR VISIT EXELONPATCHOFFER2.COM.
>> CONNECTICUT'S GOVERNOR
CALLING FOR A MOMENT OF SILENCE
THIS FRIDAY MORNING EXACT LOW
ONE WEEK AFTER THE UNTHINKABLE
HAPPENED IN THE COMMUNITY OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
26 BELLS WILL TOLL, FOR EACH
PERSON KILLED AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
DAN MALLOY GETTING VERY
EMOTIONAL TALKING ABOUT TELLING
PARENTS THEIR CHILDREN WERE
DEAD.
>> IT WAS EVIDENT TO ME THAT
THERE WAS A RELUCTANCE TO TELL
PARENTS AND LOVED ONES THAT THE
PERSON THEY WERE WAITING FOR WAS
NOT GOING TO RETURN.
THAT HAD GONE ON FOR A PERIOD OF
TIME, WELL AFTER THERE WAS ANY
EXPECTANCY THAT FAMILIES WOULD
BE REUNITED.
>> THE WOUNDS ARE STILL SO
FRESH.
TWO OF THE SLAIN CHILDREN, 6
YEARS OLD, NOAH POSNER AND JACK
PINTO ARE THE FIRST TO BE LAID
TO REST.
AS THE INVESTIGATION MOVES
FORWARD, AN OFFICIAL TOLD CNN
THE COMPUTERS IN THE HOME OF THE
GUNMAN HAD BEEN MASHED AND
AUTHORITIES GATHERED THE PARTS
HOPING TO FIND IN CLUES.
>> ANDERSON COOPER IS HELPING US
COVER THIS HORRENDOUS STORY.
HUH A CHANCE TO SPEAK WITH
PARENTS OF ONE OF THE VICTIMS?
>> LYNN AND CHRIS McDONNELL
REACHED OUT AFTER WATCHING THE
BROADCAST AND WANTED TO TALK
ABOUT THEIR DAUGHTER, GRACE, ONE
OF THE CHILDREN KILLED.
16 KIDS IN HER CLASS AND 15
SURVIVED.
GRACE DID NOT.
THEY ARE INCREDIBLY STRONG AND
THEY HAVE A SON NAMED JACK WHO
IS 12.
WE DID NOT INTERVIEW HIM.
THEY WANTED PEOPLE TO KNOW ABOUT
GRACE.
WE WILL BE PLAYING A LOT OF THAT
TONIGHT ON 360 AND THAT'S HOW WE
WILL LEAD OFF THE BROADCAST.
THEY WANT PEOPLE TO REMEMBER HER
AS THEY REMEMBER HER.
HOW SHE LIVED HER LIFE.
THELING THAT LYNN AND CHRIS
TALKED TO ME ABOUT IS HOW THEY
DON'T WANT THEIR SON HATING
ANYBODY INVOLVED IN THIS
SHOOTING.
HOW IT'S OKAY TO BE ANGRY, BUT
THEY DON'T WANT HIM TO FEEL
HATE.
I TALKED TO LYNN ABOUT THAT
EARLIER.
>> I HAD SAID THAT TO JACK THAT
IT'S OKAY TO BE ANGRY BECAUSE
SURE, WE HAVE ANGER AND WE ARE
UPSET AND WE DON'T KNOW WHY, BUT
I TOLD JACK THAT HE COULD NEVER
LIVE WITH HATE.
GRACE DIDN'T HAVE AN OUNCE OF
HATE IN HER.
WE HAVE TO LIVE THROUGH GRACE
AND REALIZE THAT HATE IS NOT HOW
OUR FAMILY IS.
CERTAINLY NOT HOW GRACE IS.
I KNOW ALL THOSE BEAUTIFUL
LITTLE CHILDREN DIDN'T HAVE ANY
HATE IN THEM EITHER.
WE WILL TAKE THE LEAD FROM THEM
FROM AND WILL NOT GO DOWN THAT
ROAD, BUT WE WILL LET THEM GUIDE
US.
>> THEY WEREN'T ABLE TO SEE
GRACE.
THEY WERE WARNED NOT TO SEE HER,
BUT THEY WENT TO THE FUNERAL
HOME AND TOLD US THE CASKET WAS
WHITE.
THEY BROUGHT MAGIC MARKERS AND
SHE AND HER HUSBAND AND SON JACK
USED THOSE MAGIC MARKERS AND
JACK SAID THEY GRAFFITIED THE
CASKET, BUT PAINTED ALL THE
THINGS THAT GRACE LOVED.
THEY LEFT THAT FUNERAL HOME
YESTERDAY AND SAID THERE WASN'T
ANY WHITE LEFT ON THE CASKET.
EVERYTHING WAS COLORED IN THE
WAY GRACE WOULD HAVE WANTED IT.
>> I HEARD OTHER TRAGEDIES I
COVERED AS YOU HAVE, THE PARENTS
WANT THE WORLD TO KNOW ABOUT
THEIR CHILD WHO WAS NEEDLESSLY
KILLED.
>> HOW THEY KNOW THEIR CHILD.
>> I WANT TO EMPHASIZE WE ARE
BEING VERY RESPECTFUL.
I AM NOT KNOCKING ON DOORS.
THEY CONTACTED US.
THEY WANT PEOPLE TO UNDERSTAND
WHAT THEY HAVE LOST.
WHAT THE WORLD HAS LOST.
THIS BRIGHT LITTLE GIRL WHO HAD
HER FUTURE AHEAD OF HER AND THEY
MET WITH PRESIDENT OBAMA JUST
YESTERDAY AND GAVE HIM A DRAWING
THAT GRACE HAD DONE OF AN OWL
AND THEY HAVE ME A COPY OF IT AS
WELL AND PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID HE
WOULD CHERISH IT AND PUT IT UP
IN THE WHITE HOUSE AND IN MY
OFFICE OR HOME.
THEY ARE AN INCREDIBLE FAMILY
AND THE STRENGTH IS SOMETHING
THAT WILL INSPIRE A LOT OF
PEOPLE.
>> WHEN YOU WATCH THAT, I CAN'T
WAIT TO SEE THE REST OF IT.
I'M AMAZE AT THEIR STRENGTH.
THEY HAVE LOST THEIR DAUGHTER
JUST DAYS AGO.
>> IT'S EXTRAORDINARY HOW STRONG
THEY ARE.
THEY ARE VERY FRANK.
THERE UPS AND DOWNS AND IT COMES
LIKE A WAVE AT TIMES.
THERE TOUGH MOMENTS AND MOMENTS
WHERE THEY TAKE COMFORT AND
STRENGTH IN THEIR LITTLE GIRL
AND THE MEMORIES THEY HAVE OF
HER.
LYNN LOOKS AT PICTURES OF GRACE,
THEY HAVE PICTURES AROUND THE
HOUSE.
THEY ARE A BEAUTIFUL FAMILY ANDY
WE ARE GOING TO REALLY HONOR
GRACE TONIGHT.
>> 8:00 P.M. EASTERN WE WILL BE
WATCHING.
THANKS VERY, VERY MUCH.
AS THE FIRST OF WHAT WILL BE
MANY FUNERAL SERVICES GET UNDER
WAY HERE, MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS
ARE POPPING UP ALL OVER NEWTOWN.
JOINING US FROM ONE OF THEM.
A SHORT DISTANCE FROM WHERE WE
ARE RIGHT NOW.
HEART FELT GESTURES HAVE A WAY
OF BRINGING HOME THE MAGNITUDE
OF THIS TRAGEDY.
DON'T THEY?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
YOU CAN SEE THE MISSION BAND
PLAYING.
-IT IS CALLED THE NATIONAL
ASSOCIATION FOR THE PREVENTION
OF STARVATION.
THEY WERE ON A MISSION AND I
WANT TO TALK TO THE FOLKS WHO
ARE HERE.
THIS IS ROARY AND RICH OUT HERE
AND WHERE ARE YOU GUYS FROM?
>> TUMBLE.
>> WHY DID YOU GUYS COME OUT?
>> I NEEDED TO SHOW RESPECT FOR
THE FAMILIES OF THIS TRAGEDY.
THAT'S THE MAIN REASON WHY I
CAME?
>> I NEEDED TO COME OUT FOR
MYSELF TOO.
IT'S TOUGH.
I REALLY WANTED TO HELP MYSELF.
>> WHY WILL IT HELP YOU?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
JUST GET THE EMOTION OUT.
IT'S HARD TO GET OUT.
HELP SEEING THIS AND ALL THE
WARMTH AND LOVE HERE IS VERY
NICE.
PEOPLE FROM ALL OVER THE COUNTRY
ARE HERE.
I THINK THAT'S OUTSTANDING.
>> LINDA, YOU HAVE BEEN OUT HERE
FOR A WHILE.
SO MANY PEOPLE HAVE COME UP AND
WE CAN BARELY GET INSIDE.
THE MEMORIAL IS MOVING CLOSER TO
THE STREET.
>> YES AND I AM FROM MONROE.
I AM VERY CLOSE TO HERE.
I FELT LIKE I WANTED TO COME
BECAUSE I WORK WITH VICTIMS OF
DOMESTIC VIOLENCE.
WITH CHILDREN WHO ARE VICTIMS OF
THEY ARE THE MOST INNOCENT --
THEY ARE SO INNOCENT AND WE HAVE
AN OBLIGATION TO PROTECT THEM.
THAT'S WHY I'M HERE.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> I DON'T KNOW IF YOU GUYS CAN
HEAR IT, BUT THE PEOPLE ARE
SINGING ON THE OTHER SIDE HERE.
PEOPLE COME OVER AND SING AND
PRAY AND HUG.
THEY JUST LOVE EACH OTHER AND AS
YOU HEAR, THESE GUYS ARE SAYING
IT IS AWESOME.
IT IS AWESOME TO SEE THIS AND
IT'S AWESOME TO SEE THAT AT
LEAST THERE IS HOPE IN THE
COMMUNITY THAT THINGS WILL ONE
DAY GET BECOME TO NORMALCY.
THAT WON'T BE ANY TIME SOON.
>> NO.
IT'S GOING TO BE A WHILE.
DON, THANKS VERY MUCH.
THESE REPORTS HE IS BRINGING US
FROM THE MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS
THAT ARE SO POWERFUL, YOU AND I
WALKED AROUND AND WE HAVE SEEN
PEOPLE COME OVER TO US.
>> EVERYONE IS HEALING TOGETHER.
>> WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH A SELECT TERRAIN DIAL
THAT ADJUSTS THE JEEP
GRAND CHEROKEE'S PERFORMANCE
FOR SPECIFIC WEATHER
AND ROAD CONDITIONS...
♪
...EVEN HEAVY SNOWSTORMS...
WON'T KEEP YOU
FROM GETTING TO WORK.
OUR APOLOGIES.
♪
>>> DR. SANJAY GUPTA IS BACK
WITH US.
YOU HAVE BEEN DOG A LOT OF
RESEARCH.
YOU HAVE BEEN DOING A LOT MORE
OVER THE PAST FEW DAYS.
HOW QUICKLY WILL THESE KIDS FEEL
SAFE ENOUGH TO GO BACK TO
SCHOOL, THE 600 KIDS AT THAT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL ATTACKED
FRIDAY MORNING?
>> THERE IS NO HARD AND FAST
RULES.
ANY EXPERT WILL SAY THAT.
I HAVE BEEN TALKING TO A LOT OF
PEOPLE AND SEEING CONSISTENCIES
AND EARLIER THE BETTER SEEMS TO
BE A MANTRA THAT I KEEP SAYING.
THE KIDS ARE GOING TO FEEL
DIFFERENT LEVELS OF SAFETY IN
PART IN TERMS OF HOW MUCH THEY
WERE EXPOSED TO THE VIOLENCE AND
WHAT THEY SAW.
THE EARLIER THE BETTER,s SOON AS
YOU CAN ESTABLISH THE NORMALCY
SEEMS TO MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
YOU CAN ACCELERATE THE FEELINGS
OF SAFETY.
EVERY CHILD WILL BE DIFFERENT,
BUT IT SEEMS TO BE SOMETHING.
>> THAT'S ONE OF THE QUESTIONS
RAISED ON HOW THEY ARE
TRANSITIONING INTO THE TEMPORARY
SCHOOL.
SOME WERE ASKING IF THEY WERE
ONLY BACK FOR A DAY BEFORE THEY
GO ON HOLIDAY BREAK, WHY WOULD
YOU DO THAT?
>> THAT'S THE POINT.
YOU REALLY DON'T WANT TO WASTE
ANY TIME.
YOU CAN DRAW TRAJECTORIES
BETWEEN THE ESTABLISHING OF
NORMALCY AND LONG-TERM OUT COME.
THE QUICKER YOU ESTABLISH THAT
NORMALCY THE BETTER IN TERMS OF
LONG-TERM OUT COME.
A QUICK FRAME OF REFERENCE,
COLUMBINE HAPPENED IN APRIL SO
NEAR THE END OF THE SCHOOL YEAR.
THEY KEPT THE SCHOOL CLOSE AND
DIDN'T OPEN UNTIL AFTER THE
SUMMER BRICK IN AUGUST.
THAT WAS A DECISION MADE IN
COLORADO AT THAT TIME.
EVERY COMMUNITY WILL HANDLE IT
DIFFERENTLY.
THOSE ARE OLDER KIDS, BUT THE
SOONER THE BETTER.
>> THE PARENTS WILL FEEL ANXIOUS
AS WELL.
THEY SAY DR. GUPTA, WHAT SHOULD
WE DO.
>> YOUNG KIDS AND DIFFERENT THAN
OTHER SITUATIONS.
THIS IS THE SITUATION IN SOME
WAYS, CHECK YOUR FEELINGS FIRST.
YOU WILL FEEL ANXIOUS AND THE
KEY THEY KEEP HEARING IS NOT TO
INCUMBER A CHILD THAT YOU TRY TO
PROVIDE SUPPORT WITH WITH YOUR
FEELINGS.
IT'S TOUGH AND PROBABLY EASIER
SAID THAN DONE, BUT MAKING SURE
YOU LISTEN AND YOU FILL IN
DETAILS AS APPROPRIATE.
LET THEM DO TALKING.
INSTEAD OF SAYING I WILL TELL
YOU EVERYTHING THAT HAPPENED,
DON'T DO THAT.
FIND OUT WHAT THEY KNOW.
THEY WILL PROBABLY KNOW THINGS
THAW DON'T REALIZE THEY KNOW.
>> SOME PARENTS WILL SAY TO A
DOCTOR, I THINK I NEED
MEDICATION.
WHAT DO THEY DO?
>> SOMETIMES IT'S NECESSARY.
WE HAVE TALKED ENOUGH ABOUT THIS
THAT I'M NOT SOMEONE WHO
ADVOCATES THAT REGULARLY, BUT
SLEEP IS SUCH A KEY.
PARRA ARE IF YOU CAN'T SLEEP IF
YOU ARE SO NERVOUS, YOU GIVE
THEM AMBIEN OR MEDICATION TO
HELP THEM SLEEP.
>> ANTI-ANXIETY MEDICATION OR
SLEEPING MEDICATION AND
SOMETIMES THAT IS NECESSARY FOR
THE ADULTS.
SOMETIMES FOR KIDS AS WELL.
IF YOU CAN GET THESE CHILDREN
GOOD SLEEP ESPECIALLY IN THE
EARLY NIGHTS, IT'S VERY, VERY
IMPORTANT.
MEDICATION HOPEFULLY IS NOT
NECESSARY BECAUSE THESE ARE
POWERFUL MEDS ESPECIALLY FOR THE
YOUNG CHILDREN.
YOU HAVE TO MAKE SURE YOU
ADDRESS THAT.
>> SANJAY, THANKS VERY, VERY
MUCH AND THANKS FOR EVERYTHING
YOU HAVE BEEN TELLING OUR
VIEWERS AS WELL.
THE MAN WHO KNEW THE LANZA
FAMILY SAID NANCY LANZA PICKED
UP THE GUN HOBBY RECENTLY.
HE IS STANDING BY TO JOIN US
NEXT.
>>> ERIN BURNETT IS HERE WITH ME
IN CONNECTICUT AS WELL.
YOU HAD A CHANCE TO SPEAK TODAY
WITH FOLKS WHO ACTUALLY KNEW THE
SHOOTER'S MOTHER?
>> YES, A RESTAURANT CALLED "MY
PLACE" WHICH YOU MAY HAVE SEEN
DRIVING AROUND IN ONE OF THE
MALLS.
IT'S SORT OF A LOCAL JOINT.
SHE WENT THERE TWO TO THREE
TIMES A WEEK TO GET TAKE-OUT,
SOMETIMES TO GET A BEER, AND SHE
GOT TO KNOW THE FAMILY WHO OWNS
IT.
THE FAMILY SAID SHE WAS
GENEROUS, HOW FUNNY SHE WAS.
SHE WAS THE PERSON WHO AT A BAR
WHO WOULD BE TELLING A STORY
ABOUT SOMETHING WAS WRONG IN
THEIR LIFE AND SHE WOULD SAY,
HERE'S SOME MONEY.
I ASKED IF SHE EVER TALKED ABOUT
HER GUN LHOBBY.
THEY SAID, YES, SHE HAD.
>> ONE OF THE THINGS WE HEARD IS
SHE WAS PASSIONATE ABOUT GUNS,
SHE COLLECTED GUNNED.
IS THAT SOMETHING YOU KNEW ABOUT
OR WERE SURPRISED WHEN YOU
HEARD?
>> I WOULD SAY IN THE LAST THREE
OR SO YEARS SHE PICKED UP THE
HOBBY.
SHE REALLY ENJOYED IT.
SHE PROBABLY HAD SOME GUNS SHE
USED TO TAKE TO THE RANGE AND
PRACTICE WITH.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT SHE OWNED OR
WHAT SHE HAD.
WE DON'T KNOW IF SHE TOOK HER
SON, DIDN'T TAKE HER SON.
SHE DIDN'T TALK ABOUT IT THAT
MUCH.
I TOOK IT UP, IT'S FUN.
THAT KIND OF THING.
>> GIVEN YOU KNEW HER AS A
PERSON, IS SHE THE KIND OF
PERSON TO HAVE GUNS AROUND THE
HOUSE, WOULD THEY HAVE BEEN
LOCKED UP?
>> THEY WOULD HAVE BEEN LOCKED
UP.
>> FAR TOO BRIGHT FOR THAT.
VERY SMART.
>> THE QUESTION ABOUT THE GUNS,
WOLF, WHY SHE HAD THEM, WHY SHE
WOULD TAKE HER SON TO A SHOOTING
RANGE, THOSE ARE QUESTIONS WE
DON'T HAVE SKWRS TO, BUT WE'RE
STARTING TO GET MORE COLOR ON
WHO SHE WAS AND WHY SHE LIKED
WHAT SHE LIKED?
>> WE'LL HAVE MORE AT THE TOP OF
THE HOUR AS WELL.
>> WE'LL BE TALKING WITH OTHER
NEIGHBORS.
ONE WOMAN WHOSE 11-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHT
DAUGHTER, HER FRIEND LOST HER
TWO SIBLINGS.
>> IT'S A HARD STORY TO COVER.
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
>> IT'S HARD.
YOU SEE THE HOLE AND THEN YOU
SEE THE PEOPLE WHO LIVE HERE AND
THE HOLE THEY HAVE AS THE
INTERNATIONAL MEDIA TAKES A BASE
IN THE TOWN.
IT'S HARD TO DO OUR JOB.
>> PEOPLE COME UP TO US AND WANT
TO TELL THEIR STORIES.
YOU HAVE SEEN THAT AS WELL.
WE'LL SEE YOU IN A MINUTE.
>> 12 GIRLS, 8 BOYS, 6 WOMEN.
THE NUMBERS ONLY BEGIN TO TELL
THE STORY.
IN JUST A MINUTE, THE NAMES,
FACES, DETAILS OF LIVES
TRAGICALLY CUT SHORT AT THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
I'M GOING TO DREAM
ABOUT THAT TIRAMISU.
WHAT A NIGHT, HUH?
BUT, UM, CAN THE TEST DRIVE
BE OVER NOW?
HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A PASSAT.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN, $0 DUE AT SIGNING,
$0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
♪ BUT THE FIRE IS
SO DELIGHTFUL ♪
NOTHING MELTS AWAY THE COLD
LIKE A HOT, DELICIOUS BOWL
OF CHICKEN NOODLE SOUP
FROM CAMPBELL'S.
♪ LET IT SNOW, LET IT SNOW
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME FOR CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
>>> THAT'S IT FOR ME TONIGHT.
I'M WOLF BLITZER.
"ERIN BURNETT OUTFRONT" STARTS
IN JUST A MINUTE, BUT WE LEAVE
YOU RIGHT NOW WITH THIS TRIB UT
TO THE VICTIMS.
>> LET THE LITTLE CHILDREN COME
TO ME, JESUS SAID, AND DO NOT
HINDER THEM, FOR TO SUCH BELONGS
THE KINGDOM OF HEAVEN.
CHARLOT
CHARLOTTE, DANIEL.
OLIVIA.
>> SHE WAS OUTGOING, SHE WAS A
BEAUTIFUL, OUTGOING CHILD.
>> TENNIS LESSONS AND HER BALLET
AND HIP-HOP DANCE AND MUSICAL
THEATER.
SHE HAD A HUGE SENSE OF HUMOR.
THIS WAS NOT A SHY CHILD.
>> JOSEPHINE.
ANA.
♪
DYLAN.
MAD
MADELEINE.
>> CATHERINE.
CHASE.
JESSE.
JAMES.
GRACE.
EMILIE.
>> HER LOVE AND THE STRENGTH SHE
GAVE US AND THE EXAMPLE SHE
SHOWED US IS REMARKABLE.
SHE IS AN INCREDIBLE PERSON, AND
I'M SO BLESSED TO BE HER DAD.
>> JACK.
NOAH.
>> NOAH WAS EXTREMELY LIVELY.
HE WAS REALLY THE LIGHT OF THE
ROOM.
YOU KNOW, HE HAD A HUGE HEART
AND HE WAS SO MUCH FUN.
A LITTLE BIT RAM BUNCHTUOUS.
LOTS OF SPIRIT.
>> CAROLINE.
JESSICA.
>> SHE WAS A BALL OF FIRE.
SHE RULED THE ROOST.
>> OUR LITTLE CEO, WE CALLED
HER.
SHE WAS THE BOSS.
>> BENJAMIN.
AVIELLE.
ALLISON.
GOD HAS CALLED THEM ALL HOME.
FOR THOSE OF US WHO REMAIN, LET
US FIND THE STRENGTH TO