WERE SET UP ON THIS LOCATION AS
WELL.
IT'S JUST A VERY SAD DEVELOPING
SCENE.
AGAIN, IT IS AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THE DEVELOPMENTS CONTINUE TO
COME IN, AND THERE'S A NEWS
CONFERENCE SCHEDULED FOR 1:00
EASTERN TIME THIS AFTERNOON.
WITH THAT, I'M GOING TO HAND OFF
THE BATON TO MY COLLEAGUE
SUZANNE MALVEAUX TO CONTINUE THE
COVERAGE.
SUZANNE.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WELCOME TO CNN NEWSROOM AND
WELCOME TO OUR VIEWERS AROUND
THE WORLD AS THEY SIMULTANEOUS
CAST THIS DOMESTICALLY AND
INTERNATIONALLY.
WE WERE BREAKING NEWS OUT OF
CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE FOLLOWING THIS SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
POLICE TOLD US A NUMBER OF
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN SHOT AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, ABOUT 60
MILES NORTH OF NEW YORK.
FIRST CALLS COMING INTO POLICE
AROUND 9:40 LOCAL TIME THIS
MORNING.
CHILDREN WERE BEING EVACUATED,
THE SCHOOLS IN THE AREA ALL ON
LOCKDOWN.
NOW, WE HAVE LEARNED THAT THE
SHOOTER IS DEAD.
WE ARE ALSO HEARING MULTIPLE
LOCAL REPORTS OF FATALITIES.
I WANT TO GO TO OUR CNN'S JASON
CARROLL FOR THE VERY LATEST.
FIRST OF ALL, OUTLINE IF YOU
WILL HOW MANY PEOPLE WE KNOW ARE
DEAD, WHO HAS BEEN KILLED, AND
WHO HAS BEEN INJURED.
>> WELL, FIRST OF ALL, LET'S GO
BACK TO THE BEGINNING.
WE STARTED TO RECEIVE REPORTS AT
ABOUT 9:40 A.M.
THAT'S WHEN POLICE, SUZANNE,
REPORTED THAT A SHOOTER WAS IN
THE, QUOTE, MAIN OFFICE OF THE
SCHOOL.
AT THAT POINT WE HAD ALSO HEARD
A REPORT THAT A PERSON IN ONE
ROOM HAD NUMEROUS GUNSHOT
WOUNDS.
THIS COMING TO US FROM ONE OF
OUR AFFILIATES THERE.
OUR SUSAN CANDIOTTI HAS
CONFIRMED THROUGH ONE OF HER
SOURCES THAT SOMEONE HAS BEEN
SHOT, THE ALLEGED GUNMAN
INVOLVED IN THE SHOOTING AT THE
SCHOOL, AND THAT TWO WEAPONS
WERE RECOVERED FROM THAT
PARTICULAR GUNMAN.
WE ARE ALSO GETTING INFORMATION
IN COMING FROM THE MAYOR, THE
MAYOR OF DANBURY, CONNECTICUT
WHO SAID THAT ACCORDING TO HIM
THREE PEOPLE TAKEN TO DANBURY
HOSPITAL.
THE NATURE OF THEIR INJURIES AT
THIS POINT UNKNOWN.
WE DID -- AS WE DIPPED INTO
LOCAL AFFILIATE COVERAGE THERE,
AS YOU SEE SOME OF THE PICTURES,
WE DID HEAR REPORTS THAT ONE
TEACHER WAS SHOT IN THE FOOT.
THAT WAS ACCORDING TO ONE
REPORTER THERE.
ALSO, ANOTHER REPORT THAT A
CHILD HAD AN INJURY TO THE FACE
AND ANOTHER CHILD WITH AN INJURY
TO THE HAND.
A FATHER ACTUALLY HAD CALLED
INTO THE CNN NEWSROOM EARLIER
TODAY, SUZANNE, AS ALL WAS THIS
WAS DEVELOPING SAYING THAT HE
SAW ONE CHILD TAKEN AWAY WITH,
QUOTE, SERIOUS INJURIES.
I CAN ALSO TELL YOU THAT A PRESS
CONFERENCE IS SCHEDULED FOR JUST
ABOUT AN HOUR FROM NOW.
THAT WILL BE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE.
AT THAT POINT HOPEFULLY WE CAN
GET MORE DETAILS CONFIRMED, SOME
MORE INFORMATION ABOUT THE
ALLEGED SHOOTER IN THIS AND MORE
DETAILS ABOUT ALL OF THOSE HURT.
SUZANNE.
>> YOU HAD MENTIONED EARLIER
THAT THERE WERE LOCAL MEDIA
REPORTS OF MULTIPLE FATALITIES.
WHERE ARE THESE REPORTS COMING
FROM?
>> ARE THESE POLICE OFFICERS OR
OFFICIALS ON THE GROUND SAYING
THEY'RE A POTENTIAL FOR MULTIPLE
FATALITIES?
IS THIS COMING FROM THE
HOSPITALS?
WHERE DO WE SUSPECT THIS
INFORMATION IS COMING FROM.
>> ONE IS COMING TO US FROM ONE
OF THE LOCAL PAPERS THERE, THE
HARTFORD CURRENT AND ANOTHER
FROM WABC.
THE ONLY DETAILS THEY GIVE AT
THIS POINT IS THAT, QUOTE,
MULTIPLE FATALITIES.
WE ARE STILL WAITING TO CONFIRM
THAT PARTICULAR REPORT.
WHAT CNN CAN CONFIRM AT THIS
POINT IS THAT AT LEAST THREE
PEOPLE TAKEN TO LOCAL HOSPITALS,
DANBURY HOSPITAL, WITH, QUOTE,
SERIOUS INJURIES.
>> JASON, WE WANT TO LISTEN IN
AND DIP IN IF WE CAN TO OUR
AFFILIATE WSFB AND THE LATEST
REPORTING THEY HAVE HERE.
>> FOR A PARENT TO RECEIVE NOT
TO GO THERE AND WAIT FOR THAT
INFORMATION.
WE KNOW THAT A MESSAGE DID GO
OUT TO PARENTS GIVING THEM SOME
INFORMATION.
HOPEFULLY P IF YOU ARE A PARENTN
THAT AREA YOU RECEIVED THAT
MESSAGE.
THE SUPERINTENDENT DID
IMMEDIATELY PUT ALL SCHOOLS IN
NEWTOWN ON LOCKDOWN.
WE HEARD SOME PRIVATE SCHOOLS IN
THAT AREA WENT ON LOCKDOWN AS
WELL.
IN ADDITION TO THAT, OUR NEW
HAVEN BUREAU CHIEF IS REPORTING
THAT MANY NEIGHBORING TOWNS ALSO
WENT INTO A HEIGHTENED STATE OF
SECURITY AT THEIR SCHOOLS AS
WELL UPON HEARING THIS AND, OF
COURSE, ONE OF THE BIG THINGS
THAT WE ARE WAITING TO HEAR AND
THAT POLICE ARE WORKING ON RIGHT
NOW IS WHAT POSSIBLE MOTIVE
COULD BE BEHIND THIS SHOOTING AT
THIS SCHOOL?
WE KNOW AT LEAST ONE PERSON
OTHER THAN THE GUNMAN HAS BEEN
SHOT, AND THE GUNMAN IS DEAD AT
THIS POINT.
>> AND AS OUR SISTER STATION IN
NEW YORK CITY IS SAYING, AT
LEAST THREE PEOPLE WERE INJURED
AND TWO CHILDREN AND ONE ADULT.
ALL THREE HAVE BEEN TAKEN IT TO
DANBURY HOSPITAL, BUT THEY SAY
THAT THEY'RE LOOKING FOR A CAR.
A MAROON OR RED-COLORED VEHICLE
WITH THE BACK WINDOW BLOWN OUT.
THAT IS GO THAT WCBS OUT OF
NEW YORK CITY IS REPORTING.
WE'RE TRYING TO GIVE YOU THE
INFORMATION COMING IN FROM SO
MANY DIFFERENT SOURCES CHOOSING
THE ONES WE KNOW TO BE THE MOST
RELIABLE WITH THE SOCIAL PRESS
AND OUR SISTERS STATIONS WCBS
WHO SAY LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS HAVE CONFIRMED THIS TO
THEM.
>> IT TO GIVE YOU AN IDEA HOW
CHAOTIC OF THE SCENE IT IS, THAT
IS JUST TO THE REAR OF FIREHOUSE
USED AS A STAGING AREA, PROBABLY
ABOUT A QUARTER-MILE DOWN THE
DRIVEWAY FROM THAT SCHOOL.
TO GIVE YOU AN IDEA, WHEN ROBERT
ARRIVED ON THE SCENE NEAR THAT
FIREHOUSE WHERE HE REPORTED LIVE
EARLIER THIS MORNING, HE
REPORTED THAT POLICE OFFICERS
CAME OUT OF THE WOODS ESCORTING
A GENTLEMAN TELLING PEOPLE HE
HAD NOTHING TO DO WITH THIS.
THAT'S THE KIND OF RESPONSE
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT WHERE ANYONE
FOUND IN THIS KRAR WAS AT LEAST
QUESTIONED BY POLICE AND THAT
THEY WANT TO TALK TO ANYONE
THERE.
POLICE ALSO JUST AS WE ARE
WORKING RIGHT NOW TO TRY TO GET
A HANDLE ON EXACTLY WHAT HAS
HAPPENED THERE.
IT LOOKS LIKE THE HELICOPTER
PICTURES ARE HAVING FREEZE-UP.
THAT'S A SHOT OF THE FIREHOUSE
WHERE THIS TOOK PLACE.
YOU CAN LOOK AT BIN POINT NEWS
TRACKER TO SEE WHAT THAT SCENE
LOOKS LIKE.
THE FIREHOUSE IS JUST ABOVE THAT
LABEL THAT SAYS DICKINSON DRIVE
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE MAP.
YOU CAN SEE THAT FIREHOUSE, AND
THAT'S WHERE ROBERT HAS BEEN
GOING LIVEND REPORTING LIVE
THIS MORNING.
SIGH THAT LONG DRIVEWAY.
THERE'S THE FIREHOUSE AND THE
WHITE BUILDING THERE AND THE
LONG DRIVEWAY INTO THE SCHOOL.
THAT'S WHERE POLICE HAVE BEEN
SWARMI
SWARMING.
>> POLICE ARE ORGANIZING TO HAVE
A NEWS CONFERENCE.
THAT TIME MAY BE MORE FLUID.
THEY'RE GOING ABOUT TWO MILES
AWAY, AND THEY REALIZE THAT THE
PUBLIC IS CERTAINLY WANTING TO
KNOW AS MUCH AS POSSIBLE,
ESPECIALLY PARENTS.
A REVERSE 911 CALL WENT OUT TO
THE RESIDENTS OF NEWTOWN
INFORMING THEM OF THIS SCHOOL
SHOOTING AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
THE DANBURY TIMES IS REPORTING
THAT STUDENTS STARTED TO HEAR
THE GUNSHOTS DURING THE MORNING
ANNOUNCEMENTS.
>> CBS IS NOW REPORTING THAT AT
LEAST ONE CHILD AT THE SCHOOL
HAS DIED AS A RESULT OF THIS
SHOOTING AT AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, SANDY HOOK LLTARY
SCHOOL.
AT LEAST ONE CHILD AT AT THAT
THAT SCHOOL HAS DIED IN THIS
SHOOTING.
SO, OBVIOUSLY, WE HAD FEARED
THAT THAT WOULD BE THE NEWS THAT
WE WOULD BE GETTING, THAT THERE
WAS MORE CASUALTIES.
WE KNOW THE GUNMAN IS DEAD.
CBS NEWS IS CONFIRMING AT LEAST
ONE CHILD DEAD AS WELL.
>> ABSOLUTELY HEART-BREAKING.
LET'S GO LIVE TO ROBERT ON THE
SCENE.
ROBERT.
>> THERE IS A LOT OF TENSENESS
HERE AND A LOT OF CONFUSION.
PARENTS JUST SHOWED UP HERE, OF
COURSE, AFTER THEY STARTED
GETTING INFORMATION THAT THERE
WAS SOME SORT OF SHOOTING
INCIDENT HERE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
YOU CAN SEE ALL THE EMERGENCY
VEHICLES AND PARENTS MIXED IN
TOGETHER.
OF COURSE, THE POLICE TRY TO
SECURE THE SCENE OVER AT THE
SCHOOL.
WE DO KNOW THAT THERE HAVE BEEN
AT LEAST SEVERAL PEOPLE SHOT.
PARENTS ARE GETTING INFORMATION
FROM EMERGENCY OFFICIALS THAT
ONE OF THOSE PEOPLE SHOT MAY BE
THE PRINCIPAL.
WE'RE TRYING TO CONFIRM THAT.
STATE POLICE ARE STAGING AN AREA
ABOUT TWO MILES FROM HERE WHERE
THEY WILL BE DOING A NEWS
CONFERENCE TO GET OUT SOME
OFFICIAL INFORMATION.
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE WILL BE
THE ONE LEADING THAT IN THE NEXT
20 TO 30 MINUTES.
OF COURSE, WE WILL BE AT THAT
NEWS CONFERENCE, BUT RIGHT NOW
OVER AT THE SCHOOL PARENTS JUST
CONFUSED.
WE'RE HEARING THAT.
THEY'RE VERY TENSE.
AS WE WERE SHOWING UP, A LOT OF
PARENTS WALKED OUT WITH THEIR
CHILDREN, VERY YOUNG CHILDREN,
THIRD, FOURTH GRADERS.
THEY WERE, OF COURSE, VERY
EMOTIONAL.
A LOT WERE CRYING.
ONE PARENT TELLING US THAT HIS
CHILD TOLD HIM THAT SOMEONE
WALKED INTO THE CLASSROOM AND
SHOT THE TEACHER.
THAT'S JUST SOME OF THE
INFORMATION.
WE ASKED THAT PARENT HOW YOUR
CHILD IS DOING.
HE WAS RUNNING UP THE STREET
SAYING, I DON'T KNOW AT THAT THE
POINT.
THEY'RE STILL TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT THAT.
THERE'S JUST A LOT OF
INFORMATION THAT'S COMING OUT.
AGAIN, THE NEWS CONFERENCE WILL
BE HAPPENING ABOUT TWO MILES
FROM HERE.
WE HAVE A CREW THERE.
WE WILL BE GETTING THAT
INFORMATION VERY SHORTLY.
HOPEFULLY TO SHED SOME LIGHT,
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCIE TELLING S
THIS IS ONE OF THE WORST
SHOOTING INCIDENTS WE'VE SEEN IN
THE STATE IN A LONG TIME.
RIGHT NOW NEWTOWN POLICE HERE
TRYING TO WORK WITH THE PARENTS.
IT SEEMS THAT STATE POLICE ARE
THE ONES THAT ARE ACTUALLY
HANDLING THE INVESTIGATION.
WE'VE SEEN FEDERAL AGENTS HERE
INCLUDING FROM THE ATF.
THERE'S A LOT OF HEAVY WEAPONRY
THAT'S BEING USED TO GO INTO
THERE.
WE ALSO ARE HEARING REPORTS THAT
AT LEAST ONE OF THE GUNMAN, IF
THERE ARE JUST -- IF THERE IS
ONE MAYBE MORE WAS SHOT AND
KILLED.
WE DON'T KNOW IF THAT WAS
SELF-INFLICTED OR HE WAS SHOT
DURING THE INITIAL RESPONSE.
EXCUSE ME.
WE'RE LIVE RIGHT NOW.
YOU CAN SEE SOME OF THE
AMBULANCES LEAVING THE AREA.
THEY'RE COMING OUT OF THE
SCHOOL.
WE KNOW THAT SEVERAL PEOPLE WERE
INJURED IN THIS, AND RIGHT NOW
WE'RE JUST TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHO.
SHE SAID AT THIS POINT THEY
DON'T HAVE DETAILS ON WHO IS
SHOT, BUT THERE ARE SOME REPORTS
THAT THERE HAVE BEEN AT LEAST
TWO FATALITIES, MAYBE MORE.
AGAIN, LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE
TELLING US IT'S ONE OF THE WORST
SHOOTINGS THEY'VE SEEN IN A LONG
TIME.
THAT NEWS CONFERENCE IS SUPPOSED
TO HAPPEN MOMENTARILY ABOUT TWO
MILES FROM HERE.
WE HAVE A CREW THERE AND BRING
THAT TO YOU LIVE.
WE'RE LIVE RIGHT NOW, CHANNEL 3
EYEWITNESS NEWS.
>> THANK YOU, ROBERT.
THIS PICTURE SO TELLING AS THE
CHILDREN ARE CRYING.
WE HAVE AN EYEWITNESS WHO WAS
THERE AT THE SCHOOL, AND JOINING
US ON THE PHONE LINE.
WE'RE JUST SPEAKING, SO IF YOU
COULD IDENTIFY YOURSELF, SIR, OR
MA'AM.
>> IT'S LIZ.
LIZ, WHAT CAN YOU TELL US?
>> I WAS BRINGING MY SON, DEVIN,
TO SCHOOL WHEN ALL THE POLICE
CARS AND EMERGENCY VEHICLES WERE
DRIVING BY.
SO MY GUT TOLD ME THAT THEY WERE
HEADED TO THE SCHOOL, AND WE
DROVE DOWN AND CONFIRMED THAT
THEY WERE HEADED TO THE SCHOOL.
THEY WERE SURROUNDING A DARK SUV
OR VAN WITH A TOOELE ON TOP, AND
THERE WAS A STRANGE BURNING
SMELL AND WE LEFT.
WE WENT HOME.
ON THE WAY WE LEARNED THAT THERE
WAS A SHOOTING AT THE SCHOOL.
THE SCHOOL PUTS OUT A BLAST, SO
I DIDN'T BRING MY SON TO HIS
SCHOOL, THE HIGH SCHOOL.
WE JUST WENT HOME WHERE FRIENDS
WHO HAVE CHILDREN IN THE SCHOOL
ASKED US TO COME TO A FRIEND'S
HOUSE THAT'S NEXT DOOR TO THE
SCHOOL AND SEE P IF WE COULD
FIND OUT ANYTHING, IF THEIR
CHILDREN WERE OKAY.
THAT'S WHERE WE MET LYNN AND
HAVE BEEN HELPING HIM.
>> LIZ, ABOUT EXACTLY --
>> WE'RE FOLLOWING THIS BREAKING
NEWS STORY.
WE HAVE STUNNING NEW DETAILS
FROM A EYEWITNESS INSIDE THE
SCHOOL.
WE'RE GOING TO BRING THAT TO YOU
AFTER WE TAKE A QUICK BREAK.
AMERICANS BELIEVE THEY SHOULD BE
IN CHARGE OF THEIR OWN FUTURE.
HOW THEY'LL LIVE TOMORROW.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
SFX- "sounds of african
drum and flute"
Look who's back.
Again?
It's embarrassing
It's embarrassing!
We can see you Carl.
We can totally see you.
Come on you're better than
this...all that prowling around.
Yeah, you're the
king of the jungle.
Have you thought about going
vegan Carl?
HAHAHA!!
You know folks who save hundreds
of dollars by
switching to GEICO
sure are happy.
How happy are they Jimmy?
Happier than antelope with
night-vision goggles.
Nice!
Get happy. Get GEICO.
Fifteen minutes could save you
fifteen percent or more.
>>> WE'RE CALLING THIS BREAKING
NEWS STORY A SCHOOL SHOOTING
THAT TOOK PLACE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WE'RABLYING IN THE MANAGING
EDITOR OF CNN.COM AND JUST SPOKE
WITH AN EYEWITNESS INSIDE OF THE
SCHOOL.
I HAVE TO WARN OUR VIEWERS, I
UNDERSTAND THAT SOME OF THE
DETAILS ABOUT WHAT SHE ACTUALLY
WITNESSED IS PRETTY GRUESOME.
MEREDITH, WHAT SHE CONVEY TO
YOU?
>> HI, SUZANNE.
SHE CONVEYED TO ME THAT SHE WAS
IN A MEETING THIS MORNING.
SHE SAID IT WAS 9:30, 9:35.
THERE WERE ABOUT SEVEN PEOPLE IN
THE ROOM, AND IT WAS A MEETING
REGARDING ONE OF HER KIDS.
SHE HAS CHILDREN AT THE SCHOOL.
SHE VOLUNTEERS AT THE SCHOOL AS
WELL.
SHE HEARD -- SHE DESCRIBED A
POP, POP, POP IN THE HALL.
THEY ALL HEARD IT.
THERE WERE ABOUT SEVEN PEOPLE IN
THE MEETING ROOM.
THEY HEARD THAT SOUND IN THE
HALL.
THEY -- SHE SAID THREE PEOPLE
WENT OUT IN THE HALL, THE
PRINCIPAL, THE VICE PRESIDENT
AND THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST, AND
TO HEAR HER DESCRIBE IT SHE SAID
THREE PEOPLE WENT OUT IN THE
HALL.
ONLY ONE PERSON CAME BACK, WHICH
WAS THE VICE PRINCIPAL SHE SAID,
WHO WAS SHOT IN THE LEG OR THE
FOOT.
SHE CAME CRAWLING BACK.
SHE SAID THAT SHE COWERS UNDER
THE TABLE DURING THAT MOMENT,
AND SHE CALLED 911, AS DID THE
OTHER PEOPLE IN THE ROOM.
SHE SAID SHE NEVER SAW THE
SHOOTER.
SHE SAID SHE WAS UNDER THE
TABLE.
THAT THE SHOOTING HAPPENED IN
THE HALLWAY, AND TO HEAR HER
DESCRIBE IT, SHE SAID THERE MUST
HAVE BEEN 100 ROUNDS.
I ASKED HER TO CLARIFY THAT,
REALLY, TRULY 100 ROUNDS?
SHE SAID AT LEAST.
>> WHEN THE VICE PRINCIPAL CAME
CRAWLING BACK, WHAT UP HAPPENED
AAT THAT POINT?
WHAT DID SHE SAY?
HOW DID THE VICE PRINCIPAL
MANAGE TO MOVE OR ESCAPE?
DID SHE DESCRIBE WHAT WAS THE
SITUATION AS HE WAS CRAWLING
BACK?
>> SHE DESCRIBED -- SHE SAID
THAT -- SHE SAID THAT THERE WAS
CONFUSION.
THERE WAS YELLING
UNDERSTANDABLY.
SHE SAID THERE WAS YELLING UNTIL
THE HALLWAY, AND SHE COULDN'T --
SHE COULDN'T TELL FOR A WHILE IF
IT WAS THE POLICE OR THE
SHOOTER.
WHEN I TALKED TO HER, SHE WAS
STILL INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
THE SCHOOL IS ON LOCKDOWN, SO
SHE COULDN'T TELL -- SHE DIDN'T
KNOW IF THE SHOOTER WAS DEAD YET
OR STILL THERE.
>> WHAT DID THE VICE PRINCIPAL
LOOK LIKE WHEN SHE SAW HIM
RETURN?
>> I DIDN'T -- I DIDN'T HEAR HER
DESCRIBE THAT.
SHE SAID -- YOU KNOW, SHE SAID,
LISTEN, THIS IS A NICE TOWN.
THIS IS NOT A NICE SCHOOL.
THESE ARE THE KINDS OF THINGS
THAT DON'T HAPPEN THERE.
SHE NOTED THIS WAS NOT SO
HIGH-POWERED MEETING.
IT WAS ABOUT MY -- ABOUT ONE OF
MY CHILDREN WHO IS IN SECOND
GRADE THERE.
YOU KNOW, SHE'S TEARFUL.
SHE'S -- YOU KNOW, JUST
UNDERSTANDABLY PANICKED.
SHE SAID THEY MARCHED AT SOME
POINT -- I DON'T HAVE THE LENGTH
OF TIME, BUT SHE SAID AT SOME
POINT AAFTER THE SHOOTING THEY
MARCHED US OUT IN THE HALLWAY
RIGHT PAST THE TWO BODIES LAYING
IN THE HALLWAY IN A POOL OF
BLOOD.
>> WHEN SHE TALKED ABOUT THE TWO
BODIES, IS THAT OF THE PRINCIPAL
AND THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST WHEN
SHE SAID THOSE TWO HAD NOT
RETURNED?
ARE THESE THE TWO INDIVIDUALS
SHE WAS TALKING ABOUT?
>> THAT'S RIGHT, THAT'S RIGHT.
>> AND DID SHE SAY OR DESCRIBE
IN ANY WAY WHAT THEIR CONDITIONS
LOOKED LIKE WHEN SHE PASSED THEM
IN THE HALLWAY?
>> NO, SHE DID NOT.
SHE DID NOT.
SHE -- WE HAD A SHORT
CONVERSATION.
SHE'S UNDERSTANDABLY EMOTIONAL.
THOSE ARE PRETTY MUCH THE GIST
OF -- THAT'S THE GIST OF OUR
CONVERSATION.
YOU KNOW, SHE WAS WONDERING HOW
CAN THE -- HOW COULD SOMEONE GET
IN?
IT'S A LOCKED SCHOOL.
YOU HAVE TO BE BUZZED IN.
>> SURE.
MEREDITH, I'M SORRY.
WERE THERE ANY KIDS IN THE
HALLWAY, ANY CHILDREN IN THE
HALLWAY AS THEY HAD MOVED PAST
THE TWO BODIES?
>> SHE SAID, YES.
SHE SAID THE CHILDREN -- SHE
SAID THERE WAS SOME CHILDREN
STILL RIGHT THERE IN THE SCHOOL
RIGHT NOW.
SOME CHILDREN HAD TO BE WALKED
PAST THAT POOL OF BLOOD.
PAST THE BODIES.
>> HOW LONG WAS SHE IN THAT ROOM
WHEN SHE HEARD THOSE GUNSHOTS
BEFORE THERE WAS SILENCE?
>> WELL, SHE SAID SHE WAS
THERE -- SHE SAID SHE GOT THERE
AT 9:00 -- SHE SAID THE MEETING
STARTED AT 9:00, 9:30.
SHE SAID THAT SHE FEELS LIKE IT
WAS RIGHT AT THE START OF THE
MEETING, SO SHE SAID AROUND
9:30, 9:35 THEY STARTED TO HEAR
THE POP, POP, POP IN THE HALL.
IT SOUNDS LIKE SHE KNEW WHAT IT
WAS.
I ASKED HER, I SAID, A LOT OF
PEOPLE DON'T KNOW THAT'S WHAT
THEY'RE HEARING, GUNSHOTS.
WE ALL KNEW SOMETHING WAS FIRED
IN THE HALL, AND THREE PEOPLE
WENT OUT AND ONLY ONE PERSON
CAME BACK.
SO THAT MEETING STARTED AT 9:30,
AND SHE'S STILLED LOCKED DOWN IN
THE SCHOOL.
>> DOES SHE HAVE ANY IDEA HOW
LONG A TIME THAT WAS WHEN SHE
WAS HEARING ALL OF THAT POPPING
NOISE, ALL THAT GUNFIRE?
>> NO.
NO.
SHE SAID IT WENT -- IT WENT --
IT WENT QUICKLY, AND THEN SHE
SAID ALTERNATIVELY, YOU KNOW, IT
WAS 100 ROUNDS THAT WENT ON
SEEMINGLY FOREVER.
>> WAS THERE ANYONE TREATING THE
PRINCIPAL AND THE PSYCHOLOGIST
WHEN THEY WERE IN THE HALLWAY?
>> SHE DIDN'T MENTION THAT.
>> DID SHE SEE ANYBODY WHO MIGHT
HAVE BEEN COMING TO THEIR AID,
OR WERE THEY JUST ESCORTED,
WALKED PAST THE TWO BODIES?
>> I BELIEVE, SUZANNE, SHE SAID
THAT SHE SAW A STRETCHER OR
SOMEONE COMING TO THEIR AID.
I THINK SHE MENTIONED SOME KIND
OF ASSISTANCE, BUT AGAIN, SHE
WAS -- HER MAIN FOCUS AT THIS
POINT WAS REALLY TO TRY TO TELL
THE STORY OF THEY WERE THERE IN
THAT ROOM, SEVEN PEOPLE, AND
WHAT HAPPENED AND HOW SHE WENT
UNDER THE TABLE AND CALLED 911.
THREE PEOPLE OUT, AND ONLY ONE
CAME BACK.
THAT WAS THE GIST OF THE STORY.
>> DID SHE DESCRIBE AT ALL,
MEREDITH, WHAT IT WAS LIKE, THE
SCENE?
WHETHER OR NOT IT WAS CALM OR
CHAOTIC WHEN THEY WERE USHERED
OUT OF THE ROOM AND OUT OF THE
SCHOOL?
>> NO, SHE DIDN'T DESCRIBE IT AS
EITHER CALM OR KAY YOT ITTCHAOT.
WHEN I ASKED HER WHAT IT WAS
LIKE, SHE SAID THEY'RE JUST
TRYING -- I ASKED IF THERE WERE
ANY MESSAGES GOING OVER THE LOUD
SPEAKER, IF THERE'S -- OF WHAT'S
BEING SAID.
SHE SAID THERE'S NOTHING LIKE
THAT HAPPENING INSIDE THE SCHOOL
RIGHT NOW.
SHE SAID EVERYONE IS STILL ON
LOCKDOWN.
SO IT'S -- SO IT SOUNDS LIKE
THEY'RE KEEPING PEOPLE, YOU
KNOW, WHERE THEY ARE.
SHE SAID THERE ARE STILL
CHILDREN IN CLASSROOMS HERE.
>> MEREDITH ARTLEY, THANK YOU SO
MUCH.
I APPRECIATE IT.
>> THANKS, SUZANNE.
>> WE'RE GOING TO TRY TO GET IN
TOUCH WITH SOME PEOPLE INCLUDING
THE WOMAN YOU SPOKE TO WHO
EXPERIENCED JUST A HARROWING
EXPERIENCE, THOSE SEVEN PEOPLE
INSIDE OF A ROOM HEARING THE
GUNFIRE AND THEN HAVING TO WALK
PAST THOSE WHO WERE SHOT IN THE
HALLWAY.
I WANT TO GO BACK TO OUR
AAFFILIATE, WFSB, FOR MORE
DETAILS.
>> I WONDER IF THAT PERSON WAS
INVOLVED.
THAT PERSON WAS TAKEN TO A
POLICE CAR.
WE DO NOT KNOW WHERE THAT PERSON
IS AT THIS POINT, AND AGAIN, WE
DO NOT KNOW IF THERE WAS ONE
SHOOTER OR MORE SHOOTERS.
THAT WILL ALL BEING SORTED OUT,
I THINK.
THEY WERE TRYING TO SECURE THIS
AREA.
THEY WERE ALLOWING US A LOT
CLOSER, BUT NOW AS THEY'VE
SECURED THE AREA, THEY'RE
EXPANDING THE ZONE AS THIS
INVESTIGATION BEGINS.
OF COURSE, WE HAVE THIS OTHER
INFORMATION THAT THEY'RE TRYING
TO TRACK A VAN, AND THEY MAY
HAVE AN AREA OVER IN DANBURY
THAT THEY HAVE THAT VAN.
SO WE OBVIOUSLY HAVE A CREW OVER
THERE AS WELL, BUT I THINK THE
MAIN INFORMATION RIGHT NOW IS
COMING FROM A NEWS CONFERENCE
WITHIN THE NEXT HALF HOUR.
CARA.
>> THANK YOU, ROBERT.
>> ROBERT, WE APPRECIATE IT.
OBVIOUSLY, WE'LL STAY ON THERE
AND BRING YOU THAT INFORMATION
AS SOON AS THAT PRESS CONFERENCE
BEGINS.
WE'LL TAKE THAT LIVE FROM
NEWTOWN.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, A K TO 4 SCHOOL WITH
ABOUT 600 STUDENTS, THE SCENE OF
A SHOOTING THIS MORNING.
ONE CHILD CONFIRMED DEAD, THE
GUNMAN DEAD AS WELL.
AT LEAST ONE OTHER PERSON WAS
SHOT, ALTHOUGH POLICE SAY THAT
THEY DO BELIEVE THAT THERE MAY
BE OTHER VICTIMS INVOLVED IN
THIS.
AT THIS POINT THE SCHOOL IS
COMPLETELY SURROUNDED BY POLICE
OFFICERS WHO RESPONDED TO THAT
AREA FROM ALL AROUND THE STATE
OF CONNECTICUT.
9:41 THIS MORNING, ABOUT THREE
HOURS AGO, THAT CALL CAME IN
REPORTING THAT SHOOTING AND FROM
THAT TIME ALL AROUND THE STATE
OF CONNECTICUT, STATE POLICE
S.W.A.T. TEAMS AND OTHER POLICE
RESOURCES HEADING THERE TO THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
YOU CAN SEE THE AMBULANCES
THERE.
AN ENORMOUS RESPONSE TO THAT
SCHOOL, AND WE DID HEAR REPORTS
WCBS REPORTING THAT THE
FIREFIGHTERS WERE HELPING TO
ESCORT CHILDREN OUT OF THE
SCHOOL.
THEY WERE TELLING THOSE CHILDREN
TO COVER THEIR EYES AND RUN AS
THEY WENT BY THE SCHOOL OFFICE.
OBVIOUSLY AN OMINOUS WARNING
HERE.
THIS IS A PICTURE FROM THE
NEWTOWN BEE SHOWING CHILDREN
ESCORTED OUT BY STATE TROOPERS.
YOU CAN SEE THE HUGE GLUT THE
VEHICLES THAT CAME IN THERE AS
PEOPLE CAME TRYING TO GET
INFORMATION.
>> VERY CHAOTIC AND HORRIFYING
SCENE FOR THE PEOPLE WHO HAVE
CHILDREN IN THAT SCHOOL.
REPRESENTATIVE JOHN FRAY IS
SERVING HIS SEVENTH TERM IN THE
CONNECTICUT HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES, THE MINORITY
WHIP.
HE SAID HIS NIECE AND NEPHEW GO
TO THAT SCHOOL, AND SHE
WITNESSED FIRST GRADERS RUNNING
FROM THE SCHOOL CRYING.
SHE AMONG OTHER PEOPLE TOOK
THOSE CHILDREN, AND PEOPLE HAVE
BEEN ASSEMBLING AT THE
FIREHOUSE.
HERE WE SEE THE PICTURES OF
ADULTS AND PRESUMABLY TEACHERS
TAKING AWAY DISTRAUGHT CHILDREN
AND WALKING THEM TO A SAFER
PLACE.
ROBERT TOLD US THAT MANY
CHILDREN HAVE REUNITED WITH
FAMILIES, BUT THEY ARE REMAINING
AT THE FIREHOUSE BECAUSE THEY'RE
UNABLE TO LEAVE THIS VERY ACTIVE
SCENE WHERE THEY'RE'S A
POSSIBILITY THEY'RE LOOKING FOR
A SECOND GUNMAN.
>> WE HAVE ON THE PHONE JESSICA
NORTON.
SHE'S WITH THE GROUP SURVIVORS
OF HOMICIDE.
THEY'RE ACTIVE IN THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT.
JESSICA, CAN YOU GIVE US SOME
IDEA JUST FROM YOUR OWN PERSONAL
EXPERIENCE AND DEALING WITH YOUR
GROUP WHAT THESE FAMILIES ARE
DEALING WITH?
>> THEY'RE ABSOLUTELY TERRIFIED
RIGHT NOW, ESPECIALLY AT THE
FACT A LOT OF THEM DON'T EVEN
KNOW WHAT IS GOING ON WITH THEIR
CHILDREN AND WHETHER OR NOT
THEY'RE SAFE.
>> WE LOST OUR AFFILIATE THERE.
WE'VE BEEN FOLLOWING THIS
BREAKING NEWS STORY, THIS SCHOOL
SHOOTING THAT TOOK PLACE AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT.
CNN CONFIRMS THAT AT LEAST TWO
HAVE DIED, INCLUDING THE
SHOOTER.
THIS TOOK PLACE IN THE MORNING
ABOUT 9:40 AT THIS ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
WE'RE GETTING MULTIPLE REPORTS
OF MULTIPLE FATALITIES.
THAT HAS NOT BEEN INDEPENDENTLY
CONFIRMED, BUT WE EXPECT A NEWS
CONFERENCE FROM LOCAL POLICE TO
OUTLINE AND TRY TO SORT OUT A
THE LOT THE DETAILS AND
CONFLICTS STORIES.
WE GET STORIES FROM PEOPLE
INSIDE OF THE BUILDING,
EYEWITNESSES AND PEOPLE WHO
HEARD THE SHOOTING.
ONE EYEWITNESS WE JUST SPOKE TO
SAYING THAT THEY HEARD 100
ROUNDS, AND THEY SAW AT LEAST
TWO PEOPLE WHO HAD BEEN SHOT AND
WHO WERE IN THE HALLWAY
BLEEDING.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A QUICK
BREAK, AND WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK
WITH MORE DETAILS.
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
>>> FOLLOWING THIS BREAKING NEWS
STORY.
WE HAVE NEW DETAILS.
THIS IS A STORY WE'RE FOLLOWING
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
OUT OF NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
WHERE A GUNMAN OPENED FIRE ON
THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL EARLY
THIS MORNING AT 9:40 LOCAL TIME.
WE ARE LEARNING THAT THREE
PEOPLE ARE DEAD FROM THIS
SHOOTING INCLUDING THE GUNMAN
ITSELF.
IT'S UNCLEAR WHETHER HE SHOT
HIMSELF OR HE WAS KILLED, BUT WE
DO KNOW AND WE HAVE FROM
EYEWITNESSES THEIR ACCOUNTS AND
THIS IS FROM PARENTS AND PEOPLE
INSIDE OF THE SCHOOL WHO TELL
THE STORY OF HEARING AT LEAST
100 ROUNDS OF GUNFIRE INSIDE THE
SCHOOL THIS MORNING.
OUTSIDE OF AN OFFICE, WE HAVE
NOW LEARNED AND CONFIRMED THAT
BOTH THE PRINCIPAL AND THE
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST HAVE BEEN
KILLED.
THAT THEY WERE SHOT INSIDE OF
THE SCHOOL, AND WE HAVE ALSO
LEARNED AS WELL A SOURCE WITH
KNOWLEDGE OF THE INVESTIGATION
THAT THE SHOOTER'S BODY IS
INSIDE A SCHOOL CLASSROOM.
THAT IS THE VERY LATEST HERE.
THERE'S STILL A LOT OF
UNANSWERED QUESTIONS ABOUT THOSE
WHO WERE INJURED.
WE HAVE REPORTS, LOCAL REPORTS
OF MULTIPLE FATALITIES.
WE NEED TO CLEAR THAT UP AND
FIND OUT JUST WHETHER OR NOT
THAT INVOLVED STUDENTS.
WE KNOW THAT THERE ARE AT LEAST
A COUPLE OF STUDENTS WHO HAVE
BEEN INJURED AND TAKEN TO LOCAL
HOSPITALS.
A TEACHER WHO WAS SHOT IN THE
FOOT, A CHILD WHO WAS -- HAS AN
INJURY TO THE FACE AND ANOTHER
CHILD WHO HAS AN INJURY TO A
HAND.
THOSE THREE, WHO HAVE BEEN TAKEN
TO DANBURY HOSPITAL.
WE ALSO KNOW FROM AN EYEWITNESS
WHO SAID INSIDE OF THE SCHOOL AT
THE TIME OF THE SHOOTING THAT
THE VICE PRINCIPAL WAS SHOT IN
THE FOOT AND CAME CRAWLING BACK
TO THE OFFICE.
THIS IS JUST UNBELIEVABLE AS WE
HEAR MORE OF THESE DETAILS, AND
WE'LL BE GETTING MORE
INFORMATION FROM A LOCAL NEWS
CONFERENCE THAT'S GOING TO TAKE
PLACE VERY SHORTLY.
WE ALSO HEARD JUST A FEW MOMENTS
AGO FROM A LITTLE GIRL WHO WAS
INSIDE OF THE SCHOOL WHEN THE
SHOOTING STARTED.
>> THIRD GRADE, AALEXIS.
YOU TOLD MEASURE YOU WERE
SITTING IN CLASS THIS MORNING,
AND YOU SAW A LOT OF POLICE.
TELL ME HOW YOU FOUND OUT WHAT
WAS GOING ON.
>> WELL, WE FOUND LIKE THERE WAS
ALL THESE PEOPLE, AND WE FOUND
IT WAS BECAUSE IT WAS LIKE NEAR
THE WINDOW IN OUR CLASSROOM.
AND LIKE WE SAW A POLICE OFFICER
AND WE HEARD THEM ON THE ROOF
AND IN OUR BUILDING.
>> WAS EVERYBODY CRYING, SCARED,
WANTING THEIR PARENTS TO COME
GET THEM?
>> YEAH, THEY ARE.
SOME PEOPLE EVEN GOT A STOMACH
ACHE.
>> DID YOU HEAR ANY GUNSHOTS OR
ANYTHING LIKE THAT?
>> WELL, POLICE OFFICERS, THEY
WERE RIGHT OUT THE DOOR TRYING
TO FIND THE GUY.
>> WE WANT TO GO TO NEWS 12, OUR
AFFILIATE NEWS 12 IN CONNECTICUT
FOR THE AERIAL SHOT AND SOME OF
THE DETAILS THAT THEY'RE
GETTING.
>> WE HAVE HELICOPTERS FLYING
ABOVE MY HOUSE CONTINUOUSLY.
>> TELL US WHAT HAPPENED JUST
SHORTLY AT 9:30 THIS MORNING.
WERE YOU IN YOUR HOME OR WHAT
WERE YOU DOING AT THE TIME?
>> I'M ON THE PHONE.
>> OKAY.
I'M SORRY.
>> THAT'S OKAY.
GO AHEAD.
ANYWAY, CAN YOU ASK THAT AGAIN.
I GOT SIDETRACKED HERE.
>> SURE.
NO PROBLEM.
AT ABOUT 9:30 THIS MORNING WHEN
THIS WAS ALL -- EMERGENCY
RESPONDERS WERE GETTING WORD OF
THIS, WHAT WAS HAPPENING AT YOUR
HOUSE?
HOW DID YOU KNOW THERE WAS A
PROBLEM?
>> I WAS TAKING THE DOGS OUT TO
GO TO THE BATHROOM, AND I
THOUGHT I HEARD A NOISE.
THEY STARTED GOING CRAZY, SO I
PUT THEM BACK IN THE HOUSE
BECAUSE I WAS ON MY WAY TO THE
GYM.
WHEN I WAS GETTING IN MY CAR, I
HEARD SIRENS GOING OFF
CONTINUOUSLY.
CAR AFTER CAR AFTER CAR.
SOME OF THEM WERE FLYING UP PAST
MY HOUSE AND COMING BACK AROUND
AGAIN AND GOING TO THE SCHOOL.
THIS HOUSE IS THREE HOUSES AWAY
FROM THE SCHOOL.
THREE HOUSES AWAY FROM THE
FIREHOUSE.
>> OKAY.
>> SO THEN I SEEN A BUNCH OF
CHILDREN WITH A COUPLE OF ADULTS
RUNNING UP THE ROAD.
THEY WERE GOING TOWARDS
TREADWELL PARK, WHICH IS UP FROM
US.
AS I WAS GETTING BACK IN MY CAR
AGAIN, BECAUSE I'M TRYING TO
FIGURE OUT WHAT'S GOING, I SEEN
FIVE CHILDREN RUNNING UP THROUGH
OUR BACK FIELDS.
>> IN OTHER WORDS, THROUGH YOUR
BACKYARD CHILDREN ARE RUNNING?
>> YEAH.
BECAUSE OUR BACKYARD IS ADJAC  T
ADJACENT, THE FURTHER FIELD IS
ADJACENT TO THE END OF THE
SCHOOL PROPERTY.
>> WERE THEY JUST RUNNING BY
THEMSELVES?
>> YEAH.
I DIDN'T SEE ANY ADULTS.
>> WE SHOULD POINT OUT THESE ARE
KIDS, KINDERGARTEN THROUGH
FOURTH GRADE.
THESE ARE YOUNG CHILDREN.
>> LITTLE CHILDREN RUNNING
THROUGH YOUR BACKYARD.
IT'S OUR UNDERSTANDING WHAT
WE'RE READING ON THE WIRE AND
FROM VARIOUS SOURCES THAT THE
CHILDREN WERE TOLD TO
IMMEDIATELY GET OUT OF THE
BUILDING.
>> YEP.
AND BY GOD, THOSE POOR LITTLE
GUY WERE RUNNING.
I WANT TO SAY THEY WERE IN
FOURTH GRADE, BECAUSE THEY
WEREN'T TINY.
>> I WANT TO INTERRUPT.
WE HAVE A REPORT.
THIS IS FROM ABC NEWS, THE
NETWORK NEWS, THAT THEY HAVE
CONFIRMED THROUGH FEDERAL AND
LOCAL OFFICIALS MORE THAN A
DOZEN PEOPLE INCLUDING CHILDREN
WERE SHOT AND KILLED IN THIS
SCHOOL.
>> WE HAVE NOT GOTTEN THAT
NUMBER AT THIS POINT.
NOTHING LIKE THAT.
WE'VE GOTTEN REPORTS OF THE
SCHOOL PRINCIPAL AND OF THE
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST AND OF THE
APPARENT SHOOTER, BUT THIS
ESCALATES THIS PARTICULAR
HORRIFIC EVENT EVEN FURTHER.
I MEAN, AFTER YOU SAW THE
CHILDREN RUNNING THROUGH YOUR
BACKYA
BACKYARD, COLIN, WHAT ELSE DID
YOU SEE FROM THAT POINT?
>> I STOPPED --
>> I WANT TO BRING BY PHONE A
SECURITY EXPERT RYE TIRED POLICE
OFFICER LOU POLUMBO.
WHY ARE WE HEARING CONFLICTING
REPORTS, SO MANY DIFFERENT
REPORTS FROM THOSE WHO ARE
INJURED AND THOSE KILLED FROM
VARIOUS AFFILIATES AND NETWORKS
AND PEOPLE WHO ARE ON THE
GROUND?
I ASSUME IT'S A FLUID AND
CHAOTIC SITUATION.
>>LE WE WELL, THE PROBLEM SUZAN
THE FACT THAT YOU HAVE PEOPLE AT
THE SITE, INVESTIGATORS
CONDUCTING DIFFERENT TASKS.
IN OTHER WORDS, SOME PEOPLE ARE
IN THERE TRYING TO MAKE AN
ACCOUNTING FOR WHO HAS BEEN
SHOT.
OTHER PEOPLE ARE INTERVIEWING
PEOPLE.
ANYTIME YOU HAVE ANY TYPE OF
INCIDENT, EVEN SOMETHING FAR
MORE SIMPLE THAN THIS, IT'S
DIFFICULT TO GET THE SAME
STORIES STRAIGHT OUT OF TWO
PEOPLE.
THIS IS NOTHING INCONSISTENT.
THE PROBLEM SIMPLY HE STATED IS
THEY PUT THE PIECES OF THIS
TOGETHER AS WE SPEAK, AND THAT'S
WHAT HAS SOME INCONSISTENCIES IN
REPORTING.
>> WITH ALL OF YOUR YEARS OF
EXPERIENCE, WHAT IS TAKING PLACE
ON THE GROUND NOW?
WHAT ARE THEY TRYING TO DO?
WHAT ARE THE PRIORITIES?
WHAT IS MOST IMPORTANT?
>> THE PRIORITY RIGHT NOW IS TO
IDENTIFY ANYBODY THAT'S BEEN
INJURED TO GET THEM TREATED.
WHAT THEY'RE DOING AND THEY DO
THIS IN A SOMEWHAT SIMULTANEOUS
FASHION AND THEY RESPOND, THEY
BUILD OUT A PERIMETER AND EMPLOY
CONTAINMENT AND START TO CONDUCT
AN INVESTIGATION.
THEY HAVE TO FACILITATE ENTRY.
THEY HAVE TO IDENTIFY WHO THE
SHOOTER IS, DETERMINE IF THERE
ARE EXPLOSIVES.
TIE IN WHETHER OR NOT THIS COULD
POSSIBLY OCCUR IN ANOTHER
SCHOOL, WHICH IS WHY THE SCHOOL
DISTRICTS HAVE BEEN CLOSED.
THE AREA HAS BEEN CLOSED.
THERE'S A NUMBER OF TASKS THAT
THEY'RE DOING.
BUT THE MOST IMPORTANT ONE IS
TRYING TO GET AID TO THOSE
INJURED OR POSSIBLY FATALITIES.
>> IS IT IMPORTANT -- WE'VE
HEARD VARIOUS REPORTS FROM
PEOPLE INSIDE THE BUILDING THAT
THERE'S CHILDREN IN THE BUILDING
AND CHILDREN HAVE BEEN EVACUATED
AND ADULTS ARE STILL IN THE
BUILDING, THAT THE BODY OF THE
SHOOTER IS IN A CLASSROOM.
SHOULD THESE CHILDREN HAVE BEEN
MOVED?
SHOULD PEOPLE BE OUT OF THE
BUILDING, ON OR IS IT BEST AT
THIS POINT FOR EVERYBODY TO STAY
PUT INSIDE OF THE SCHOOL?
>> I THINK THE MOST IMPORTANT
THING IS THAT EVERYONE FOLLOW
THE INSTRUCTIONS OF THE LAW
ENFORCEMENT AGENCY THAT'S IN
CHARGE.
THERE ARE REASONS THAT CHILDREN
MAY OR MARY NOT BE MOVED.
THIS IS A CRIME SCENE.
THEY'RE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT HAPPENED.
SOME OF THE CHILDREN DETAINED AT
THE SCHOOL MAY NOT BE ABLE TO
HAVE SOME TYPE OF FACILITATION
TO GET THEM OFF THE PROPERTY AND
INTO A SAFE ENVIRONMENT.
YOU CAN'T SECOND-GUESS WHAT
THEY'RE DOING THERE AT THIS
POINT.
WHAT YOU HAVE TO REALIZE IS THIS
IS AN IMMENSE UNDERTAKING, AND
IT'S PARTICULARLY SENSITIVE
BECAUSE IT INVOLVES CHILDREN.
THEY'RE TRYING TO MAKE AS FEW
MISTAKES AS POSSIBLE AND
IMPOSSIBLE NOT TO MAKE SOME.
THERE'S A METHOD TO THE MADDEN.
MOEFL A
MOST OF ALL THIS IS A CRIME
SCENE.
THEY HAVE TO DETERMINE HOW MANY
SHOTS WERE FIRED AND WHERE THEY
WERE DIRECTED.
THEY'RE TRYING TO RECOVER ANY
CASINGS, EXAMINE WALLS AND OTHER
MATERIALS THAT HAVE PROJECTILES
LODGED IN THEM.
THEY'RE TRYING TO DETERMINE WHAT
FIREARMS WERE USED.
IT'S A BROAD UNDERTAKING.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WE APPRECIATE IT.
WE'LL HAVE MANY MORE DETAILS
AFTER A QUICK BREAK.
♪ OOH BABY,
CAN I DO FOR YOU TODAY? ♪
[ Female Announcer ] NEED HELP
KEEPING YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE?
ALIGN CAN HELP.
ONLY ALIGN HAS BIFANTIS,
A PATENTED PROBIOTIC
THAT NATURALLY HELPS MAINTAIN
YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE.
TRY ALIGN TO HELP RETAIN
A BALANCED DIGESTIVE SYSTEM.
TRY THE #1 GASTROENTEROLOGIST
RECOMMENDED PROBIOTIC.
ALIGN.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OUR TENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
>>> SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT A SCHOOL
SHOOTING THAT TOOK PLACE THIS
MORNING.
FIRST CALLS GETTING IN ABOUT
9:30 LOCAL TIME.
WHAT WE'RE WATCHING HERE, THIS
IS NEWS 12 CONNECTICUT.
THIS IS ROB REPORTING.
YOU SEE AERIAL SHOTS OVERLOOKING
THE SCHOOL.
CNN CAN INDEPENDENTLY CONFIRM
THAT THE SHOOTER IS DEAD AND AT
LEAST TWO EMPLOYEES OF THE
SCHOOL HAVE BEEN KILLED.
WE WANT TO DIP INTO THE RAW
COVERAGE FROM OUR AFFILIATE.
WE CAN'T CONFIRM THE RAW LIVE
REPORTING THAT THEY ARE DOING,
BUT WE WANT TO GET A GOOD LOOK
ON THE GROUND AND GET A SENSE OF
WHAT THEY'RE LEARNING.
>> IT SEEMS AS IF THAT SCENE HAS
QUIETED DOWN NOW.
THAT IS THE VEHICLE THAT THEY
SEEM TO BE INTERESTED IN, THAT
BLACK HONDA.
IT WAS TAPED OFF VERY EARLY ON
IN THE WHOLE INCIDENT, AND YOU
CAN SEE A POLICE DOG TAKEN OVER
TO THE CAR.
THIS IS FOOTAGE FROM EARLIER
TODAY.
I KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON.
THEY'RE LOOKING FOR A SCENT, AND
THERE IS A REPORT FROM ANOTHER
TELEVISION STATION IN
CONNECTICUT THAT TWO GUNMEN WERE
INVOLVED, AND ONE WAS LED AWAY
IN HANDCUFFS.
>> SO THE EARLY REPORT OF TWO
GUNMEN AND THEN NOW WITH -- THE
ABC AFFILIATE REPORTING THAT
THAT -- THAT OTHER SECOND GUNMAN
TAKEN AWAY IN HANDCUFFS.
AT THIS POINT ALL THE
INFORMATION WE'VE RECEIVED IS
THAT THE SHOOTER -- THE FATALITY
WAS AN ADULT.
THERE ARE NO REPORTS OF --
>> BUT THERE ARE ADDITIONAL
REPORTS FROM OTHER STATIONS,
OTHER NEWS ORGANIZATIONS SAYING
AS MANY AS 20 CHILDREN MAY HAVE
BEEN SHOT.
>> I'M TALKING ABOUT THE GUNMAN,
THOUGH.
>> THIS HAS GOTTEN SO MUCH WORSE
AS WE'VE BEEN COVERING IT SINCE
WE'VE BEEN ON A COUPLE OF HOURS.
>> LET'S GO TO JAY CARNEY AT THE
WHITE HOUSE BRIEFING.
HE'S TALKING ABOUT THE SHOOTING.
>> WE'LL BEGIN TO INVESTIGATE
THIS INCIDENT.
AS I SAID, THE PRESIDENT WILL
RECEIVE REGULAR UPDATES AS THE
DAY PROGRESSES.
WE'LL TAKE YOUR QUESTIONS.
>> JAY, ONE FOLLOW-UP ON THAT.
CAN YOU RELAY TO US ANY OF THE
PRESIDENT'S REACTIONS OR
THOUGHTS?
OBVIOUSLY, ALL OF SHOOTINGS ARE
TRAGIC.
WE'RE HEARING PARTICULARLY
HEINOUS NUMBERS WHERE CHILDREN
ARE INVOLVED.
>> I WOULD RATHER NOT RELAY
REACTIONS AT THIS POINT, BECAUSE
I DON'T HAVE ANY CONFIRMATION TO
GIVE TO YOU ABOUT WHAT EXACTLY
HAS HAPPENED THERE OR POTENTIAL
VICTIMS.
AT THIS POINT I'D RATHER JUST
INFORM YOU THAT THE PRESIDENT
HAS BEEN INFORMED ABOUT THE
SHOOTING, WAS INFORMED AT 10:30
AND IS BEING GIVEN REGULAR
UPDATES AS MORE INFORMATION IS
AVAILABLE.
>> WILL WE HEAR FROM HIM TODAY?
>> WE'LL HAVE TO KEEP YOU
UPDATED AS MORE INFORMATION
BECOMES AVAILABLE.
>> Reporter: TWO OTHER TOPICS.
IN THE ABC NEWS INTERVIEW THE
PRESIDENT WAS ASKED ABOUT THE
LEGALIZATION OF MARIJUANA IN A
COUPLE OF STATES WHERE VOTERS
HAVE SOUNDED OFF ON THAT AND
ESSENTIALLY SAID THAT IT'S NOT A
HIGH PRIORITY FOR HIM, NO PUN
INTENDED, TO GO AFTER
RECREATIONAL USERS.
OBVIOUSLY, THIS IS A SERIOUS
ISSUE.
STATES RIGHTS VERSUS FEDERAL
RIGHTS.
I'M WONDERING IF THERE'S ANY
CONCERN --
>> THEY WERE LOOKING FOR
APPARENTLY ANOTHER SHOOTER.
WE DON'T KNOW HOW MANY PEOPLE
WERE INVOLVED.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS BEEN
INFORMED OF THE SHOOTING BY HIS
STAFF.
HAPPENED ABOUT 10:30 OR SO THIS
MORNING.
IT IS TYPICAL THAT AT A SCENE
LIKE THIS, A SITUATION THAT THE
PRESIDENT WOULD BE INFORMED
RATHER QUICKLY.
THAT HE WOULD BE GETTING REGULAR
UPDATES FROM HIS STAFF, AND AT
SOME POINT DEPENDING ON HOW
SERIOUS THE SITUATION IS, HE
SAID CERTAINLY THE PRESIDENT
WOULD RELEASE A STATEMENT AND
EVEN PERHAPS COME OUT PUBLICLY
TO ADDRESS WHAT HAS TAKEN PLACE
IN THINGS OF THIS NATURE.
A NATIONAL TRAGEDY OF THIS
NATURE.
I WANT TO DIP BACK INTO NEWS 12
CONNECTICUT, OUR AFFILIATE, TO
LISTEN TO SOME OF THE THINGS
THEY'RE HEARING.
>> TAKEN TO DANBURY HOSPITAL.
THE SHOOTER FOR THE MOST PART
HAS BEEN CONFIRMED.
THE APPARENT SHOOTER IS DEAD, AN
ADULT.
TWO HANDGUNS, TWO 9 MILLIMETER
GUNS RECOVERED.
STUDENTS SENT RUNNING FROM THIS
SCHOOL.
WE HEARD COLLEEN POUNDSTONE, WHO
LIVES THREE HOUSES AWAY SAYING
CHILDREN WERE RUNNING IN THE
FIELDS, WHICH ESSENTIALLY IS HER
BACKYARD.
ONE LITTLE BOY SAYING I JUST
WANT TO GO HOME.
SUCH A DISTURBING SCENE, BUT
UNFOLDING SO QUICKLY THIS
MORNING.
AS THOUGH STUDENTS ARE MAKING
THEIR WAY TO THE SANDY HOOK
VOLUNTEER FIRE DEPARTMENT, WHICH
IS NOT VERY FAR FROM THE SCHOOL.
>> NO.
YOU'VE BEEN SEEING IT.
WE'LL POINT IT AGAIN.
IT'S JUST TO THE RIGHT OF THAT
FACILITY, WHICH IS THE SCHOOL,
IS THE VOLUNTEER FIRE
DEPARTMENT, WHICH IS WHERE THE
ALL THE KIDS WERE LED, THOSE
THAT DIDN'T FLEE ON THEIR OWN.
THEY WERE MARCHED OVER THERE IN
LINE.
WE ACTUALLY HAD A PICTURE
EARLIER OF THAT, OF THE KIDS
ARMED ON EACH OTHER'S SHOULDERS
WALKING IN A LINE.
THAT'S WHERE THEY WERE TAKEN AND
THAT'S WHERE PARENTS WENT TO
MEET THEIR KIDS AND TAKE THEM
HOME.
WE THOUGHT EVERYTHING WAS GOING
GOOD.
AS THE STORY UNFOLDED IT SOUNDED
LIKE THE SHOOTER WAS SHOT AND
THEN POSSIBLY ONE OTHER PERSON.
NOW THIS HORRIBLE MOUNTING DEATH
TOLL INVOLVING SO MANY CHILDREN
AND ADULTS.
IT DOES GIVE ONE PAUSE.
>> YES.
BUT FEDERAL AUTHORITIES, AS WE
HEARD EARLIER FROM THE ASSISTANT
FIRE CHIEF.
NOW EMERGENCY RESPONDERS ARE SO
CAREFULLY CHOREOGRAPHED TODAY.
SO HE -- THOUGH HE SAID MY
KNOWLEDGE ON THIS IS LIMITED,
BUT I WILL TELL YOU THAT FBI AND
SECRET SERVICE WILL BE INVOLVED
IN THIS.
AT WHAT POINT I'M NOT CLEAR.
>> THE FBI HAS BEEN ON THE
SCENE.
>> THE LOCAL AUTHORITIES HAND
THIS OVER, AND MAYBE ATF AS WELL
ARE PART OF THIS.
>> THERE HAVE BEEN S.W.A.T.
TEAMS.
WE'VE SEEN THEM.
>> POLICE DOGS.
>> THERE IS AN UNCONFIRMED
REPORT THAT AN ENTIRE CLASSROOM
OF KIDS IS UNACCOUNTED FOR
OUTSIDE THE SCHOOL.
>> BUT THAT MAY BE THE KIDS
FLEEING THROUGH THE WOODS.
>> THAT RAN ON THEIR OWN.
>> RIGHT.
>> THE SAD, I THINK, PROBABLY
ONE OF THE REALITIES FROM
SOMETHING LIKE THIS IS
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL CHILDREN NOW
WILL BE TAKING ON A WHOLE NEW
KIND OF -- IT WON'T BE JUST THE
FIRE DRILL FROM THIS POINT
FORWARD.
A SAD REALITY, BUT IT VERY MUCH
MAY BE PART OF THEIR SCHOOL
YEAR, TRAINING FOR AN EVACUATION
IN THE EVENT OF SOMETHING AS
HORRIFIC AS THIS.
>> CBS NEWS -- THIS IS THE
NETWORK REPORTING 27 DEAD.
27 DEAD.
COLUMBINE HAD 15 THE PRODUCER
SAID, 15 INCLUDING THE SHOOTER.
>> THIS WILL TAKE US TO THE
WORST SCHOOL SHOOTING IN THE
HISTORY OF THE UNITED STATES.
ON A QUIET FRIDAY, VERY PRETTY,
CHILLY, LATE FALL DAY.
MOST PEOPLE GO INTO THEIR FRIDAY
MORNING WITH SOMEWHAT MORE
LIGHT-HEARTED THINKING HERE WE
ARE, A WEEKEND, A HOLIDAY
WEEKEND, SHOPPING, SANTA CLAUS,
THE FINAL NIGHT OF HANUKKAH.
COMING UP THIS WEEKEND, AND THEN
TO HAVE A HORRIFIC SHOOTING LIKE
THIS TAKE PLACE WITH SUCH YOUNG
CHILDREN.
>> CNN CANNOT INDEPENDENTLY
CONFIRM WHAT YOU'VE HEARD ON THE
AAFFILIATES.
THEY HAVE GOTTEN SECOND-HAND AS
WELL WHAT THEY ARE HEARING IN
TERMS OF THE DEATH TOLL.
I WANT TO BRING IN SUSAN
CANDIOTTI FOLLOWING AND TALKING
TO LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS ON
THE VERY LATEST.
I UNDERSTAND WE'VE LOST THE
CONNECTION.
WE'RE GOING TO GET BACK TO SUSAN
IN A MOMENT.
LET'S DIP BACK INTO OUR
AFFILIATE, NEWS 12.
>> CHOPPER 12 WILL BE BACK LIVE
ANY MINUTE NOW, BECAUSE I'M
GUESSING THEY FUELED UP AT THE
DANBURY AIRPORT, WHICH IS NEARBY
THERE.
IN JUST ABOUT 10 MINUTES WE WILL
HAVE FOR YOU LIVE THE NEWS
CONFERENCE FROM A PARK NOT THAT
FAR.
IT'S THAT WOMAN WE SPOKE WITH --
>> COLLEEN POUNDSTONE.
>> SHE'S GOING TO RUN UP TO THAT
PARK.
>> SHE WANTED THEM ON THE ROAD,
BECAUSE JUST RUNNING THROUGH THE
WOODS WITH EMERGENCY POLICE.
WE SAW A PHOTOGRAPH EARLIER OF
POLICE COMBING THROUGH THE WOODS
IN THAT AREA.
SHE WAS THE WIFE OF A MILITARY
MAN, AND SHE HAD MANY BRIEFINGS
ON TERRORISM PREPAREDNESS.
>> WE'LL BRING IN SUSAN
CANDIOTTI SPEAKING WITH LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS.
SUSAN, WHAT HAVE WE LEARNED THIS
MORNING?
>> Reporter: SOME HEART-BREAKING
NEWS FROM A LAW ENFORCEMENT
SOURCE WITH KNOWLEDGE OF THE
INVESTIGATION THAT CLOSE TO 20
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN KILLED AT THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING AND AMONG THEM
AT LEAST 10 ARE CHILDREN,
SUZANNE.
THIS IS NEW INFORMATION COMING
TO YOU FROM A LAW ENFORCEMENT
SOURCE WITH KNOWLEDGE OF THE
INVESTIGATION.
WE DO KNOW THAT THE SUSPECTED
SHOOTER'S BODY WAS DISCOVERED IN
A CLASSROOM, BUT WE DO NOT KNOW
HOW THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER DIED,
WHETHER IT WAS BY HIS OWN HAND
OR BY POLICE OR IN SOME OTHER
WAY.
THAT INFORMATION WE'RE STILL
WAITING FOR, AND THERE IS A NEWS
CONFERENCE COMING UP TO BE HELD
BY THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE.
WE KNOW THAT THE GOVERNOR'S
OFFICE HAS BEEN MONITORING THIS
SITUATION THROUGHOUT.
THEY ARE IN CLOSE CONTACT WITH
POLICE AS WELL, BUT THIS IS, OF
COURSE, TERRIBLE NEWS ABOUT THE
IDENTITY OF THOSE WHO ARE
KILLED, BOTH ADULTS AND
CHILDREN.
AT LEAST 10 OF THEM ARE
>> THAT IS JUST DEVASTATING TO
HEAR.
SUSAN, DO WE HAVE A SENSE IN
THIS PRESS CONFERENCE THAT IS
GOING TO OCCUR IN ABOUT TEN
MINUTES OR SO WHETHER OR NOT
THAT NUMBER COULD BE EVEN
HIGHER?
>> Reporter: I AM HEARING THAT
THAT MAY BE THE CASE.
WE ALSO HAVE ACCORDING TO
ANOTHER SOURCE THAT THE PASCHOO
PRINCIPAL WAS AMONG THOSE KILLED
AS WELL.
YES.
AS A MATTER OF FACT, HERE AT THE
SITE WE VERY RECENTLY SAW
FEDERAL, LOCAL OFFICIALS AS
WELL, LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS
WITH GUNS AT THEIR SIDE
SEARCHING -- CONTINUING TO
SEARCH THE AREA AROUND THE
SCHOOL
THEY APPEAR TO BE LOOKING AT
VARIOUS CARS.
WE DON'T KNOW WHETHER THEY ARE
SEARCHING FOR SOMEONE
SPECIFICALLY, BUT WE KNOW FROM
EARLIER INFORMATION WE HAD THAT
PROTECTIVELY THEY CONTINUED TO
LOOK THROUGH THE AREA TO MAKE
SURE THAT EVERYONE CONNECTED TO
THE SHOOTING WAS FOUND.
STILL NO KIND OF MOTIVE HAS BEEN
REVEALED AT THIS TIME.
>> SUSAN, IS THERE ANY SENSE
FROM THOSE WHO YOU'RE SPEAKING
WITH WHETHER OR NOT THOSE WHO
WERE TRAGICALLY KILLED, IF THIS
TOOK PLACE IN ONE PARTICULAR
PART OF THE SCHOOL?
COULD IT HAVE BEEN ONE CLASSROOM
OR SOMETHING WHERE THEY BELIEVE
THE GUNMAN WENT FROM CLASS TO
CLASS?
>> Reporter: WE JUST DON'T KNOW.
IT'S TOO EARLY.
OF COURSE, THOSE ARE AMONG THE
DETAILS THAT WE HOPE TO LEARN AS
WELL AS WHO THE SHOOTER WAS,
WHAT THE CONNECTION WAS, IF ANY,
BETWEEN THE SHOOTER AND THE
SCHOOL.
THOSE ARE AMONG SO MANY
QUESTIONS THAT WE ALL HAVE RIGHT
NOW.
>> DO WE HAVE ANY SENSE OF
WHETHER OR NOT THE PARENTS OF
THESE CHILDREN HAVE BEEN
NOTIFIED ABOUT THEIR CHILDREN?
>> Reporter: NO INFORMATION
ABOUT THAT EITHER.
WE DO KNOW THAT WHEN A LOT OF
CHILDREN WERE LET OUT OF THE
SCHOOL, AND I'M SURE YOU'VE SEEN
THE PICTURES OF THEM IN A LINE
WITH HANDS ON EACH OTHER'S
SHOULDER OF THE CHILD IN FRONT
OF THEM THAT ONE OF THE STAGING
AREAS IS A NEARBY FIREHOUSE.
WE HAVE ALSO SEEN SOME CHILDREN
AND PARENTS IN THE VICINITY OF
THE SCHOOL ALSO WALKING ABOUT
NOT ON THE SCHOOL SITE.
IN ANY CASE WE ARE SURE AS THEY
HAVE DONE IN SO MANY CASES PRIOR
TO THIS TRYING TO GET COUNSELING
AVAILABLE FOR CHILDREN AS SOON
AS POSSIBLE.
>> I CAN ONLY IMAGINE THE FEAR
AND CONCERN WHEN PEOPLE HEAR
THESE NUMBERS.
IS THERE ANY SENSE OF A PROCESS
OR SOME SORT OF WAY OF GETTING
INFORMATION TO PEOPLE, TO
PARENTS AND TO CHILDREN ABOUT
THE STATE OF THEIR LOVED ONES IN
THAT SCHOOL?
>> WELL, I DON'T KNOW EXACTLY
WHAT KIND OF PROCESS THEY HAVE
SET UP OR SYSTEM THAT THEY SET
UP HERE FOR THE CHILDREN.
OF COURSE, THE POLICE WERE ON
THE SCENE VERY QUICKLY.
THEY HAVE BEEN MAKING SURE THAT
THEY WERE SHUTTLING THE CHILDREN
TO A SAFE LOCATION, AND I'M SURE
AMONG MANY THINGS THEY ARE DOING
IS TO GET AS MUCH INFORMATION TO
THE PARENTS AS IS POSSIBLE, BUT
WE DON'T HAVE ANY OF THOSE
DETAILS YET EITHER.
WE ARRIVED ON THE SCENE A SHORT
TIME AGO, SO WE TRY TO CONTINUE
TO GET THAT INFORMATION FOR YOU.
>> DO YOU HAVE ANY SENSE ON THE
SCENE WHETHER OR NOT PARENTS ARE
AWARE OF THE NUMBER OF PEOPLE
AND CASUALTIES AND THE FACT THAT
TEN CHILDREN HAVE BEEN KILLED?
>> Reporter: I DO NOT, SUZANNE.
THIS IS BRAND-NEW INFORMATION,
SO I HAVEN'T HAD A CHANCE TO
SAMPLE ANY OPINIONS OR FIND OUT
FROM ANYONE IN THE AREA WHETHER
THAT INFORMATION IS WIDELY
AVAILABLE AS OF YET.
>> SUSAN, FINALLY, CAN YOU GIVE
US A SENSE OF WHAT IT IS LIKE?
WE'RE LOOKING AT LIVE PICTURES,
OF COURSE.
WE SEE A LOT OF THE EMERGENCY
PERSONNEL AND HAVE SEEN PICTURES
WITH CHILDREN AND WORRIED
PARENTS.
WE SEE FOCUS ON ONE PARTICULAR
VEHICLE THAT HAS BEEN CORDONED
OFF.
GIVE US A SENSE OF WHAT IT IS
LIKE THERE CLOSE TO THE SCHOOL
AND CLOSE TO THOSE OFFICIALS WHO
WILL SOON SPEAK WITH US ABOUT
SOME OF THE DETAILS THEY'VE JUST
LEARNED.
>> WELL, YOU CAN IMAGINE IT'S
JUST -- IT'S BEEN DESCRIBED IN
THE IMMEDIATE AFTERMATH AS
CHAOS, AND NOW THERE IS JUST
UTTER SADNESS AND SHOCK THAT YOU
SEE ON THE FACES OF PEOPLE WHO
CLEARLY AND UNDERSTANDABLY ARE
SHAKEN BY WHAT HAS HAPPENED
HERE, NOT TO MENTION AS YOU
INDICATED, SUZANNE, WHAT THESE
CHILDREN WHO MAY HAVE WITNESSED
THIS AND CERTAINLY WOULD HAVE
HEARD IT AND HAVE BEEN QUICKLY
HURRIED OUT OF THAT SCHOOL AS
SOON AS IT WAS SAFE TO DO SO,
WHAT THEY WILL BE GOING THROUGH.
THE TRAUMA THAT HAS BEEN HEAPED
UPON THEM AS WELL AS THIS
COMMUNITY.
SO ALL OF THAT WILL BE PLAYED
OUT, OF COURSE, IN THESE FEW
SHORT HOURS.
THERE IS STILL A LOT OF POLICE
ACTIVITY IN THE AREA AS WE
CONTINUE TO SEE FEDERAL, STATE
AND LOCAL LAW ENFORCEMENT
AUTHORITIES WALKING ABOUT NOT
ONLY AROUND THE SCHOOL BUT ALSO
SOME SURROUNDING BUSINESSES
ARNO
AROUND THE AREA.
THEY'RE CHECKING CARS AND
LOOKING AROUND.
YOU GET A SENSE THAT THEY ARE
CHECKING TO MAKE SURE AND SOME
OF MY SOURCES HAVE TOLD ME THAT
THE AREA IS SECURE.
>> ALL RIGHT.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
WE APPRECIATE IT.
OF COURSE, WE ARE FOLLOWING THIS
BREAKING NEWS STORY, SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL OUT OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, NOT FAR
FROM NEW YORK.
WE HAVE JUST LEARNED REALLY
DEVASTATING NEWS THAT 20 PEOPLE
KILLED IN THIS SCHOOL SHOOTING,
INCLUDING 10 CHILDREN.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A QUICK
BREAK.
WE'RE WAITING FOR A POLICE
BRIEFING THAT WILL HAPPEN VERY
SHORTLY.
Searching for a bank designed
for investors like you?
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Schwab Bank was built with all
the value and convenience
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
investors want.
Like no ATM fees, worldwide.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
And no nuisance fees.
Plus deposit checks with
Mobile Deposit.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
And manage your cash
and investments
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
with Schwab's mobile app.
No wonder Schwab Bank has grown
to over 70 billion in assets.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
So if you're looking for a bank
that's in your corner,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
not just on the corner...
Call, click or visit to start
banking with Schwab Bank today.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN DIARRHEA HITS,
KAOPECTATE STOPS IT FAST.
POWERFUL LIQUID RELIEF
SPEEDS TO THE SOURCE.
FAST.
[ Male Announcer ]
STOP THE UH-OH FAST
WITH KAOPECTATE.
>>> WE'LL GO TO NEWS 12
CONNECTICUT OUR AFILL HE YAT TO
LEARN MORE ABOUT THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING WE'RE FALLING IN
NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT.
NOW CONFIRMED 20 PEOPLE KILLED
IN THE SCHOOL SHOOTING.
LET'S LISTEN IN.
>> THAT CLEARLY IS NOW WHERE
THEY WERE STAGING.
YOU COULD SEE A NUMBER OF
AMBULANCES.
WE SAW STRETCHERS.
WE ACTUALLY SAW SOMEONE TAKEN
AWAY ON A STRETCHER FROM THAT
AREA.
THIS IS THE WOODS AND PROBABLY
THAT WOMAN WE SPOKE WITH LIVES
RIGHT IN THAT AREA.
>> UH-HUH.
>> SHE SAID SHE WAS ADJACENT TO
THE PLAYING FIELDS.
>> YOU CAN SEE THE WIDE SPACE.
>> THAT MIGHT BE HER HOME.
>> AND SHE KIND OF ECHOED THE
REALITY THAT YOU TRY AND HELP
CHILDREN TODAY, BUT THEY'RE SO
RELUCTANT.
>> SHE WAS WISE.
SHE SAID YOU DON'T HAVE TO COME
IN THE HOUSE, BUT GET ON THE
MAIN ROADS.
THOSE KIDS DID NOT WANT TO
REMAIN.
WE HAVE AN UPDATE ON THE
PRESIDENT BEING INFORMED.
A WHITE HOUSE SPOKESPERSON SAYS
THAT THE PRESIDENT FEELING
ENORMOUS SYMPATHY FOR THE
FAMILIES OF THE CHILDREN, AND
THEN WHEN ASKED ABOUT GUN
CONTROL POLICIES, THE
SPOKESPERSON SAYS THERE IS, I AM
SURE, WILL BE RATHER A DAY FOR
DISCUSSION OF THE USUAL
WASHINGTON POLICY DEBATES, BUT I
DON'T THINK TODAY IS THAT DAY.
>> NO.
THIS IS A TRAGEDY OF HISTORIC
PROPORTION, A NATIONAL TRAGEDY
NOW AS WE LEARN THAT THE DEATH
TOLL IS 27.
OF THE 27, 18 CHILDREN.
WE KNOW THAT THEY'RE VERY YOUNG
CHILDREN BECAUSE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY IS A SCHOOL THAT HAS
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADERS.
SO VIRTUALLY BABIES ATTEND
VERY -- SO YOUNG ATTEND AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL THAT IS NOT
EVEN K THROUGH 8.
IT'S K THROUGH 4 AT THIS SCHOOL.
SO HORRIFIC, HORRIFIC NEWS THAT
WE ARE ALL LEARNING.
THE SHOOTER -- THIS IS THE --
THERE WERE REPORTS OF TWO,
BUT -- ONE OR TWO SUSPECTS.
ONE IS DEAD, ONE TAKEN AWAY IN
HANDCUFFS.
THE ONE WE'RE ASSUMING WITH THE
TIES TO NEW JERSEY WHOSE HOME
THE FEDS ARE IN THE PROCESS OF
RAIDING WE ASSUME THAT IS THE
DECEASED GUNMAN.
WE DON'T KNOW AT THIS POINT.
>> WE DON'T KNOW.
THAT IS THE OTHER FACILITY WE
WERE TELLING YOU ABOUT.
THE VOLUNTEER FIREHOUSE.
YOU CAN SEE ALL THE VEHICLES
THERE IN THE TOP THERE ABOVE THE
BUILDING.
YOU CAN SEE A FIRE TRUCK TAKEN
OUT OF THE BUILDING.
IN THE MIDDLE OF YOUR SCREEN IS
WHERE ALL THE AMBULANCES
GATHERED.
WE WANT TO REITERATE THIS WAS
SHOT A COUPLE OF HOURS AGO NOW.
THIS IS WHERE THE CHILDREN WERE
TAKEN FOLLOWING THE SHOOTING.
THEY WERE LED BY STAFF MEMBERS
PROBABLY THROUGH THE WOODS THERE
THAT YOU SEE IN THE BOTTOM OF
YOUR SCREEN TO THAT AS A STAGING
AREA.
THEN EVENTUALLY PARENTS CAME TO
LEAD THEIR CHILDREN AWAY.
AT SOME POINT IN THIS VIDEO WE
DID SEE AN AMBULANCE TAKING AWAY
SOMEONE ON A STRETCHER.
LOTS OF VEHICLES THERE.
THAT'S ALSO WHERE THE MEDIA
GATHERED, AND WE'RE TOLD THAT
ABOUT A HALF HOUR AGO ALL THE
MEDIA WERE ASKED TO LEAVE THAT
AREA.
THAT'S THE SCHOOL.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU HEARD IT.
WE'RE TOLD THAT ALL OF THE NEWS
12s ARE WATCHING THIS NOW.
IF YOU JUST ARE JOINING US, THAT
SCHOOL CONSISTS OF 600 STUDENTS
FROM KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADE.
SHORTLY AFTER THE SCHOOL DAY
BEGAN, ONE REPORT SAYS DURING
THE ANNOUNCEMENTS THAT WERE
BEING MADE OVER THE LOUD SPEAKER
SYSTEM THE SHOTS BEGAN RINGING
OUT.
BEFORE ALL WAS SAID AND DONE, 18
CHILDREN AND 9 ADULTS WERE
KILLED.
>> I CAN ONLY IMAGINE AT IN THE
POINT IF THE REPORTS THAT WE
RECEIVED --
>> WE BRING IN SUSAN CANDIOTTI.
WHAT ARE YOU LEARNING ON THE
GROUND?
>> Reporter: WE'RE GETTING READY
FOR A NUPZ CONFERENCE TO START
ANYTIME NOW HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
WE ARE A SHORT DISTANCE AWAY
FROM WHERE THE SCHOOL IS
LOCATED, AND THERE IS STILL A
CRIME SCENE THERE, VERY ACTIVE
CRIME SCENE AT THIS TIME.
WE KNOW THAT THERE ARE MULTIPLE
PEOPLE DEAD, AT LEAST 20, AND
AMONG THEM AT LEAST, AT LEAST 10
OF THOSE DEAD ARE CHILDREN IN
THIS HORRIFIC SHOOTING.
THE OTHER INFORMATION IS THAT
THE SHOOTER WAS DISCOVERED IN A
CLASSROOM.
WE DON'T KNOW WHETHER HE TOOK
HIS OWN LIFE OR WAS KILLED BY
POLICE OR IN SOME OTHER WAY.
STILL WAITING TO GET THAT
INFORMATION AS WELL.
IT IS A HEART-BREAKING SCENE
HERE AS CHILDREN WERE LED
THROUGH THE SCHOOL ONE HAND ON
THE SHOULDER OF THE CHILD IN
FRONT OF THEM AS THEY ARE LED
AWAY FROM HERE, TAKEN TO A LOCAL
FIREHOUSE.
MANY OF THEM MEETING ALREADY
WITH THEIR PARENTS WHO WERE
NOTIFIED.
MANY OF THEM HAD SIGNED UP AND
LEARNED ABOUT THIS TRAGEDY BY
TEXT, THAT THERE WAS A SHOOTING
AT THE SCHOOL OR E-MAIL NOTIFIED
TO ABOUT WHAT HAD HAPPENED HERE.
MANY OF THOSE PARENTS, OF
COURSE, SHOWING UP QUICKLY TO
COMFORT THEIR CHILDREN AND BE
WITH THEIR CHILDREN AS POLICE
CONTINUE TO LOOK AROUND THIS
SCENE.
>> SUSAN, ARE THERE STILL
CHILDREN INSIDE OF THE SCHOOL?
>> Reporter: WE DON'T BELIEVE
SO, BUT I DON'T HAVE ANY
OFFICIAL CONFIRMATION ON THAT.
THIS HAPPENED AT ABOUT 9:40 OR
SO EASTERN TIME.
POLICE RATHER QUICKLY RESPONDING
TO THE SCENE OF MULTIPLE GUN THE
SHOTS AND INJURIES.
IMMEDIATELY AS SOON AS IT WAS
SAFE FOR THEM TO DO SO
CHILDREN -- FIRST THE SCHOOL WAS
LOCKED DOWN, WHICH IS USUALLY
THE CASE.
ONCE IT WAS SAVE TO LEAD THE
CHILDREN OUT OF THE SCHOOL,
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED.
WE HAVE LOCAL POLICE, STATE
POLICE, AS WELL AS FEDERAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT ON THE SCENE HERE,
INCLUDING THE FBI AND ATF.
THEY'RE CANVASSING THE AREA TO
MAKE SURE THERE WAS ONLY ONE
SHOOTER, SUSPECTED SHOOTER
INVOLVED IN THIS TERRIBLE
MASSACRE AS WELL AS WHETHER
THERE WAS ANYONE ELSE INVOLVED.
TO THAT END THEY'VE BEEN WALKING
DOWN THE STREET LOOKING AT
VARIOUS CARS.
ONE CAR IS CORN DONED OFF AND
TAPED OFF AND THEY'RE LOOKING
AROUND THE AREA AS WELL TO MAKE
SURE THEY HAVE -- THAT THERE'S
ONLY ONE SUSPECT INVOLVED IN
THIS CASE.
>> ALL RIGHT.
SUSAN, WE'RE GOING TO GET TO YOU
AND CERTAINLY GOING TO TAKE THAT
PRESS CONFERENCE AS SOON AS IT
HAPPENS, BUT I WANT OUR VIEWERS
TO LISTEN TO THIS BECAUSE THIS
WAS JUST MOMENTS AGO.
OUR CNN DIGITAL MANAGING EDITOR
MEREDITH ARTLEY SPOKE WITH US
AND TALKED TO A WOMAN WHO HAS A
SECOND GRADER INSIDE OF THAT
SCHOOL WHO WAS THERE, WHO
WITNESSED THE SHOOTING.
I WANT YOU TO LISTEN TO THIS.
>> SHE WAS IN A MEETING IN
MORNING.
THERE WERE ABOUT SEVEN PEOPLE IN
THE ROOM.
IT WAS A MEETING REGARDING ONE
OF HER KIDS.
SHE HAS CHILDREN AT THE SCHOOL.
SHE VOLUNTEERS AT THE SCHOOL AS
WELL.
SHE HEARD -- SHE DESCRIBED A
POP, POP, POP IN THE HALL.
THEY ALL HEARD IT.
THERE WERE ABOUT SEVEN PEOPLE
MOUNTAIN MEETING ROOM.
THEY HEARD THAT SOUND IN THE
HALL, AND THEY -- SHE SAID THREE
PEOPLE WENT OUT INTO THE HALL,
THE PRINCIPAL, THE VICE
PRINCIPAL AND SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST.
TO HEAR HER DESCRIBE IT, SHE
SAID THREE PEOPLE WENT OUT INTO
THE HALL, AND ONLY ONE -- ONLY
ONE PERSON CAME BACK, WHICH WAS
THE VICE PRINCIPAL, SHE SAID,
WHO WAS SHOT IN THE LEG OR THE
FOOT.
HE CAME CRAWLING BACK.
SHE SAID THAT SHE COW ERED UNDE
THE TABLE DURING THAT MOMENT,
AND SHE CALLED 911, AS DID THE
OTHER PEOPLE IN THE ROOM.
SHE SAID SHE NEVER SAW THE
SHOOTER, THAT SHE WAS UNDER THE
TABLE.
THAT THE SHOOTING HAPPENED IN
THE HALLWAY, AND TO HEAR HER
DESCRIBE IT, SHE SAID THAT THERE
MUST HAVE BEEN 100 ROUNDS.
I ASKED HER TO CLARIFY THAT,
REALLY, TRULY, 100 ROUNDS?
SHE SAID AT LEAST.
>> WHEN THE VICE PRINCIPAL CAME
CRAWLING BACK, WHAT HAPPENED AT
THAT POINT?
WHAT DID SHE SAY?
HOW DID THE VICE PRINCIPAL
MANAGE TO MOVE OR ESCAPE?
DID SHE DESCRIBE WHAT WAS THE
SITUATION AS HE WAS CRAWLING
BACK?
>> SHE DESCRIBED -- SHE SAID
THAT -- SHE SAID THAT THERE WAS
CONFUSION, THERE WAS YELLING
UNDERSTANDABLY.
SHE SAID THERE WAS YELLING IN
THE HALLWAY, AND SHE COULDN'T
TELL FOR A WHILE IF IT WAS THE
POLICE OR THE SHOOTER.
WHEN I TALKED TO HER, SHE WAS
STILL INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
THE SCHOOL IS ON LOCKDOWN, SO
SHE COULDN'T TELL -- SHE DIDN'T
KNOW IF THE SHOOTER WAS DEAD YET
OR STILL THERE.
>> WHAT DID THE VICE PRINCIPAL
LOOK LIKE WHEN SHE SAW HIM
RETURN?
>> I DIDN'T HEAR HER DESCRIBE
THAT.
SHE SAID -- YOU KNOW, SHE SAID,
LISTEN, THIS IS A NICE TOWN.
THIS IS A NICE SCHOOL.
THESE ARE THE KINDS OF THINGS
THAT DON'T HAPPEN THERE.
SHE NOTED THIS WAS NOT SOME
HIGH-POWERED MEETING.
IT WAS ABOUT ONE OF MY CHILDREN
WHO IS IN SECOND GRADE THERE.
AND SHE'S TEARFUL.
SHE'S UNDERSTANDABLY PANICKED,
AND SHE SAID THEY MARCHED AT
SOME POINT -- I DON'T HAVE THE
LENGTH OF TIME, BUT SHE SAID AT
SOME POINT AFTER THE SHOOTING
THEY MARCHED US OUT IN THE
HALLWAY RIGHT PAST THE TWO
BODIES LAYING IN THE HALLWAY IN
A POOL OF BLOOD.
>> UNBELIEVABLE.
SEVEN PEOPLE IN AN OFFICE THERE
AND EXPERIENCING SOMETHING AS
TRAGIC AS THAT.
I WANT TO BRING IN SUSAN
CANDIOTTI.
SUSAN HAS BEEN REPORTING IT
COULD BE AS MANY AS 20 PEOPLE
WHO HAVE BEEN KILLED IN THIS
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
OF THEM 10 AND WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT LITTLE CHILDREN, K THROUGH
FOURTH GRADE WHO WERE MARCHED
OUT OF THAT SCHOOL.
SUSAN, WHAT DO WE KNOW?
WHAT DO WE EXPECT TO LEARN NOIN
THE MOMENTS AHEAD FROM THIS NEWS
CONFERENCE?
>> Reporter: WE HOPE TO GET MORE
DETAILS ABOUT HOW THIS HAPPENED,
IF THEY HAVE A PRECISE NUMBER
ABOUT HOW MANY ARE DEAD, AS YOU
SAID.
WE HAVE OUR SOURCE WITH
KNOWLEDGE OF THE INVESTIGATION
SAYING THERE ARE AT LEAST 20
DEAD OR CLOSE TO 20 DEAD, AND AT
LEAST 10 OF THEM BEING CHILDREN
IN THIS GRADE SCHOOL AS YOU
MENTIONED GRADES KINDERGARTEN
THROUGH THE FOURTH GRADE.
WE KNOW THEY FOUND AT LEAST TWO
GUNS WITH THE SHOOTER, ACCORDING
TO ANOTHER SOURCE WITH KNOWLEDGE
OF THE INVESTIGATION.
TWO WEAPONS.
WE DON'T KNOW HOW THE SHOOTER
DIED, WHETHER HE TOOK HIS OWN
LIFE OR WHETHER SOMEONE ELSE
KILLED HIM.
AS SOON AS IT WAS SAFE, AS YOU
HEARD, FOR CHILDREN TO LEAVE THE
SCHOOL, THE CHILDREN WERE LED
OUT OF THE SCHOOL TO A NEARBY
FIREHOUSE THAT'S BEING USED AS A
STAGING AREA FOR CHILDREN AND
PARENTS THAT RUSHED TO THE SITE
AS SOON AS THEY COULD, JUST A
TERRIBLE, HEART-BREAKING
INFORMATION.
THE SHOCK FOR THESE CHILDREN AND
PARENTS AND THIS ENTIRE
COMMUNITY ARE GOING THROUGH NOW
TO TRY TO UNDERSTAND HOW THIS
COULD HAVE HAPPENED, IF A MOTIVE
HAS BEEN DISCOVERED FOR WHY THIS
HAPPENED, WHETHER THERE WAS ANY
CONNECTION BETWEEN THE SUSPECTED
SHOOTER IN THIS CASE AND THE
SCHOOL ITSELF THAT LED THAT
PERSON TO THE SCHOOL THIS
MORNING.
THESE ARE ALL SOME OF THE MANY
QUESTIONS THAT WE ALL HAVE.
>> ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A QUICK
BREAK HERE AND TRY TO GET
ANSWERS TO THOSE QUESTIONS AS
SOON AS WE GET TO THAT NEWS
CONFERENCE EXPECTED MOMENTARILY.
ANNCR: Some politicians seem to
think Medicare and...
Social Security are just numbers
in a budget.
Well, we worked hard for those
benefits.
We earned them.
And if Washington tries to cram
decisions about the future...
of these programs into a last
minute budget deal...
we'll all pay the price.
AARP is fighting to protect
seniors with responsible...
solutions that strengthen
Medicare and...
Social Security for generations
to come.
We can do better than a last
minute deal...
that would hurt all of us.
trying to find a better job can
Likbe frustrating.gs,
So at University of Phoenix
we're working with a growing
list of almost two thousand
corporate partners -
companies like Microsoft,
American Red Cross and Adobe -
to create options for you.
Not only that, we're using what
we learn from these partners
to shape our curriculum, so that
when you find the job you want
you'll be a perfect fit.
Let's get to work.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN DIARRHEA HITS,
KAOPECTATE STOPS IT FAST.
POWERFUL LIQUID RELIEF
SPEEDS TO THE SOURCE.
FAST.
[ Male Announcer ]
STOP THE UH-OH FAST
WITH KAOPECTATE.
>>> FOLLOWING THIS BREAKING NEWS
STORY AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
CNN IS CONFIRMING 20 PEOPLE HAVE
DIED IN THAT SHOOTING INCIDENT.
LE I'LL GO TO WABC, OUR
AFFILIATE THERE.
THEY'RE TALKING ABOUT CONDITIONS
OF SOME BROUGHT TO DANBURY
HOSPITAL.
WE WANT TO REMIND PEOPLE, WE ARE
HEARING MANY DIFFERENT NUMBERS
IN TERMS OF FATALITIES.
THIS IS RAW INFORMATION COMING
IN.
CNN CAN ONLY CONFIRM 20
FATALITIES AT THIS TIME.
LET'S LISTEN IN.
>> LIZ AND DAVE, YOU'VE BEEN
RAISING A LOT OF ISSUES ABOUT
THE WHOLE ISSUE OF SECURITY
SINCE COLUMBINE AND THE FACT OF
THE MATTER IS WE HAVE RECEIVED
THIS LETTER THAT THE PRINCIPAL
OF THE SCHOOL, DONE HASHBRUNG,
WHO WAS APPOINTED IN 2010, SENT
TO PARENTS EARLIER IN YEAR AND
I'M GOING TO READ IT TO YOU, AT
LEAST THE FIRST PART.
DEAR MEMBERS, OUR DISTRICT IS
IMPLEMENTING A SECURITY SYSTEM
IN ALL ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS AS
PART OF THE ONGOING EFFORTS TO
ENSURE STUDENT SAFETY.
AS USUAL EXTERIOR DOORS ARE
LOCKED DURING THE DAY.
EVERY VISITOR WILL BE REQUIRED
TO RING THE DOORBELL AT THE
FRONT ENTRANCE AND THE OFFICE
STAFF WILL USE A VISUAL
MONITORING SYSTEM TO ALLOW
ENTRY.
THEN THIS IS HIGHLIGHTED HERE.
VIEWERS WILL BE REQUIRED TO
REPORT TO DIRECTLY TO THE OFFICE
AND SIGN IN.
IF OUR OFFICE STAFF DOES NOT
RECOGNIZE YOU, IT GOES ON TO SAY
YOU WILL BE REQUIRED TO SHOW IFK
WITH A PICTURE I.D.
PLEASE UNDERSTAND WITH NEARLY
700 STUDENTS AND OVER 1,000
PARENTS REPRESENTING 500 SANDY
HOOK FAMILIES, MOST PARENTING
WILL BE ASKED TO SHOW
IDENTIFICATION.
A LITTLE LATER ON IT SAYS, THERE
MAY BE A SHORT DELAY UNTIL
SOMEONE CAN VIEW YOU ON THE
HANDSET AND ALLOW YOU TO COME IN
ELECTRONICALLY.
OF COURSE, WE HAVE BEEN TALKING
ABOUT THE POSSIBILITY OF A
PARENT BEING INVOLVED HERE, BUT
CLEARLY THERE ARE SECURITY
MEASURES THAT ARE IN PLACE, THAT
WERE IN PLACE THIS YEAR SO IT
WOULD BE VERY STRICT FOR ANY
VISITORS GETTING INTO THE
SCHOOL.
>> VERY STRICT.
DO WE KNOW WHY THEY WERE
IMPLEMENTED?
>> WE DON'T KNOW WHY.
WE JUST HAVE THIS LETTER, BUT
CLEARLY, AS A NUMBER OF
ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS HAVE DONE AND
A NUMBER OF HIGH SCHOOLS AS
WELL, WE'RE ALL PARENTS.
THEY'VE TAKEN THIS VERY
SERIOUSLY.
MOST OF THEM WHEN YOU DO GO INTO
THE SCHOOL NOW, YOU HAVE TO SIGN
IN.
I REMEMBER WHEN OUR SON WAS IN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, WE HAD TO GO
IN, SIGN IN, SIGN OUT WHEN YOU
LEFT.
SO CLEARLY, YOU KNOW, SCHOOLS
HAVE BEEN ADDRESSING THIS.
THIS SCHOOL DID AS WELL.
I THINK THAT'S IMPORTANT TO
MENTION HERE, BUT YOU KNOW IF
YOU'RE DEALING WITH A PARENT,
WHO KNOWS.
>> SO TRUE.
THANK YOU.
NICK, I WOULD THINK THAT MOST
ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS IN THIS
COUNTRY WHEN THEY THINK OF
SECURITY, THEY THINK OF MAYBE A
PARE
PARENTAL CUSTODY CASE, THINGS
LIKE THAT.
NOT SOMETHING AS VIOLENT AS
THIS.
BEFORE WE GET TO THAT POINT,
WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE
SHOOTER FROM ABC NEWS.
THEY TELL CRISCO MOW THAT ONE
SHOOTER WAS 24 YEARS OLD ARMED
WITH FOUR WEAPONS AND WEARING A
BULLETPROOF VEST.
POLICE ARE CONTINUING TO
INVESTIGATE THE POSSIBILITY OF
AN ADDITIONAL SHOOTER, AND STATE
POLICE HAVE CONFIRMED TO ABC
NEWS THIS AFTERNOON THAT THE TWO
SHOOTERS WERE INITIALLY BELIEVED
TO BE INVOLVED IN THIS SHOOTING.
RIGHT NOW WE'RE LEARNING THAT
THE ONE SHOOTER, 24 YEARS OLD
AND WEARING A BULLETPROOF VEST
AS WELL AS ARMED WITH FOUR
WEAPONS.
>> THAT'S JUST OUTRAGEOUS, BUT
TO GO TO THE REPORT ON THE
LETTER FROM THE SCHOOL, I MEAN,
LOOK, IT'S REASONABLE WHAT THEY
DID.
THEY ADDRESSED THE SECURITY
ISSUES.
THEY TOOK EXCELLENT PRECAUTIONS.
>> YOU'VE BEEN LISTENING IT TO
WABC THERE.
I WANT TO, AGAIN, REMIND OUR
VIEWERS, THIS IS RAW REPORTING.
THIS IS REPORTING FROM VARIOUS
NETWORKS.
CNN CANNOT INDEPENDENTLY CONFIRM
SOME OF THOSE FACTS THAT YOU'RE
HEARING THERE.
WE'RE WAITING FOR A PRESS
CONFERENCE.
YOU'LL HEAR FROM POLICE
OFFICIALS DIRECTLY ABOUT WHAT
THE ULTIMATE FATALITY COUNT IS,
THOSE INJURIED AND HOW MANY
SUSPECTS AND WHO IS INVOLVED.
WE'LL EXPECT THE NEWS CONFERENCE
TO HAPPEN VERY SHORTLY.
[ sniffs ] I HAVE A COLD.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
PROGRESSIVE DIRECT AND OTHER
CAR INSURANCE COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
CALL OR CLICK TODAY.
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
CONNECTING
TO THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
>>> SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IS THE SITE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT OF A MASSIVE
SHOOTING.
AT LEAST 20 PEOPLE KILLED.
OF THOSE KILLED 10 CHILDREN.
JUST A FEW MINUTES AGO WE HEARD
FROM A LITTLE GIRL EARLY THIS
MORNING WHO WAS ACTUALLY INSIDE
OF THE SCHOOL WHEN THAT SHOOTING
STARTED.
>> ALEXIS, YOU TOLD ME YOU WERE
SITTING IN CLASS THIS MORNING
AND SAW A LOT OF MISS.
TELL ME HOW YOU FOUND OUT WHAT
WAS GOING ON?
>> WELL, WE FOUND THERE WAS ALL
THESE PEOPLE, AND WE FOUND OUT
WE WERE RIGHT NEAR THE WINDOW IN
OUR CLASSROOM.
WE SAW LIKE POLICE OFFICERS AND
WE HEARD THEM ON THE ROOF AND IN
OUR BUILDING.
>> Reporter: WAS EVERYBODY
CRYING, SCARED, WANTING THEIR
PARENTS TO COME GET THEM?
>> YEAH, THEY WERE.
AND THEN SOME PEOPLE WERE EVEN
LIKE -- THEY KIND OF GOT A
STOMACHACHE.
>> Reporter: DID YOU HEAR ANY
GUNSHOTS OR ANYTHING LIKE THAT?
>> POLICE OFFICERS, THEY WERE
THERE KIND OF, BECAUSE THERE
WERE POLICE OFFICERS RIGHT OUT
THE DOOR TRYING TO FIND THE GUY.
>> JOINING US BY PHONE IS
SECURITY EXPERT RETIRED NASSAU
COUNTY, NEW YORK POLICE OFFICER
LOU PALUMBO.
WE WERE SPEAKING EARLIER TODAY
ABOUT HOW THE WHOLE MORNING
UNFOLDED AND WORST NIGHTMARES
COMING TRUE HERE WHEN YOU LISTEN
TO THE SUSPECTED NUMBER OF
FATALITIES, AT LEAST 20 KILLED,
OF THOSE 10 CHILDREN.
HOW DOES THIS EVEN COMPARE, I HE
MEAN, TO WHAT WE'VE EXPERIENCED
IN THE PAST?
IT'S JUST UNBELIEVABLE.
>> YOU'RE ASKING ME, SUZANNE,
HOW THIS COMPARES TO PRIOR
INCIDENTS?
>> YES.
>> I THINK IT'S ESCALATED.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT A DEATH TOLL
WITH CHILDREN TO THIS MAGNITUDE,
I DON'T KNOW HOW MUCH WORSE IT'S
GOING TO GET.
I WILL TELL YOU UNEQUIVOCALLY
WITH THIS DEATH TOLL WE'VE
SURPASSED PRIOR INCIDENTS, OF
WHICH APPROXIMATELY SEVEN IN THE
LAST COUPLE OF YEARS.
I CERTAINLY HOPE WE DON'T HAVE A
REPEAT OF THIS OR ANYTHING THAT
OUTDOES THIS, SO TO SPEAK.
>> I CAN'T EVEN IMAGINE WHAT
HAPPENS NEXT.
AS A LAW ENFORCEMENT EXPERT, CAN
YOU EXPLAIN TO US WHERE DO YOU
BEGIN?
WHERE DO YOU START HERE IN TERMS
OF THE CHILDREN, THEIR SAFETY,
THE PARENTS, IDENTIFYING THE
DEAD?
WHAT HAPPENS NOW?
>> WHAT THEY'RE DOING RIGHT NOW
IS TO -- NOT TO BE TRITE ABOUT
IT, BUT THEY'RE PUTTING THE
PIECES OF THIS TOGETHER ON MANY
LEVELS, AS YOU JUST ALLUDED TO.
THEY'RE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHO
IS DEAD.
THEY'RE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
NOTIFICATIONS.
THEY'RE TRYING TO RUN A CRIME
SCENE AND CREATE A PROFILE ON
THE INDIVIDUAL WHO PERPETRATED
THIS.
THEY'RE TRACKING DOWN THESE
FIREARMS THAT WERE IN HIS
POSSESSION TO DETERMINE HOW HE
WAS CAPABLE OF OBTAINING THEM.
SUZANNE, YOU KNOW, I HAVE TO SAY
THIS TO YOU.
I THINK WE HAVE TO GAIN SOME
SENSIBILITY IN OUR CULTURE.
THIS IS THE SEVENTH OR EIGHTH
INCIDENT INVOLVING FIREARMS, AND
I SUPPORT THE SECOND AMENDMENT.
I DON'T THINK THAT THAT'S WHAT
THIS IS ABOUT.
IT'S QUITE APPARENT THAT PEOPLE
ARE ABLE TO OBTAIN FIREARMS WHEN
THEY ARE NOT IN THE RIGHT STATE
OF MIND.
I THINK WE NEED TO HOW WOULD YOU
SAY IMPOSE PART OF THE VETTING
PROCESS SIMILAR TO ONE WE GO
THROUGH THIS LAW ENFORCEMENT TO
INCLUDE MINNESOTA MULTIPHASE
ZWICK HE SCREENING TEST.
>> WE HAVE TO GET BACK TO YOU.
I HEAR YOUR POINT.
WE'LL GO DIRECTLY IT TO WABC AND
DIP IN ON SOME NEWS THAT THEY'RE
LEARNING.
>> COME FROM A SCENE AND HUG
EACH OTHER SO EARLY ON IN THEIR
INVESTIGATION.
SO CLEARLY A VERY TELLING
MOMENT.
YOU CAN -- ONE CAN ONLY IMAGINE
THE CARNAGE INSIDE THAT SCHOOL
THAT YOU ARE LOOKING AT DOWN
THERE.
DAN RICE IN NEWS CHOPPER 7.
THANKS FOR THE UPDATE.
IT'S 1:25 IN THE AFTERNOON.
WE'RE CONTINUING TO FOLLOW THE
TRAGIC STORY OUT OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT THAT STARTED AROUND
9:30 THIS MORNING.
A GUNMAN WALKING INTO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
FROM WHAT WE KNOW NOW, THE
LATEST, 27 PEOPLE HAVE BEEN
KILLED, MOSTLY CHILDREN.
>> THE GUNMAN BELIEVED TO BE IN
HIS 20s.
HE HAD AT LEAST TWO GUNS ON HIM.
THEY WERE RECOVERED AAT THE
SCENE.
HE WAS WEARING ALL BLACK
ACCORDING TO OUR SOURCES AND A
BULLETPROOF VEST.
>> MOST OF THE CHILDREN -- THE
SCHOOL WAS EVACUATED.
THOSE CHILDREN WERE TAKEN TO A
NEARBY FIREHOUSE EARLY THIS
MORNING.
MOST OF THE PARENTS BEING ABLE
TO PICK UP THEIR CHILDREN THERE,
BUT NOW THIS WAIT, THIS
AGONIZING WAIT FOR THOSE PARENTS
WHO HAVE NOT BEEN ABLE TO LOCATE
THEIR CHILDREN.
AS MANY AS 18 CHILDREN MAY BE
DEAD.
OTHER SCHOOLS IN THE AREA,
MONROE SCHOOL DISTRICT REMAINS
ON LOCKDOWN AT THIS HOUR.
DANBURY HOSPITAL WHERE THREE OF
THE VICTIMS WERE TAKEN TO ALSO
ON LOCKDOWN AT THIS HOUR WITH AN
ABUNDANCE OF CAUTION.
INVESTIGATORS -- DAN RICE SHOWED
US THIS MINIVAN A SHORT TIME
AGO.
IT'S A SECOND CAR IN THE PARKING
LOT THAT INVESTIGATORS HAVE
CORDONED OFF AND ARE PAYING
PARTICULARLY CLOSE ATTENTION TO.
YOU CAN SEE THE OFFICERS THERE.
WE UNDERSTAND THE FBI, ATF, AND
LOCAL POLICE ALL NOW CONVERGING
IN THIS -- ONTO THIS ONE LITTLE
TOWN IN FAIRFIELD COUNTY,
CONNECTICUT.
>> INITIALLY THERE WAS SOME
CONCERNS OR QUESTIONS IF THERE
WAS MORE THAN ONE PERSON
INVOLVED PRIMARILY BECAUSE
PEOPLE WERE RUNNING FROM THE
SCHOOL AND THEY HAD TO QUESTION
WHETHER SOME OF THE PEOPLE
RUNNING WERE INVOLVED AND THE
CHAOS OF THE MOMENT.
THEY ARE PURSUING EVERY LEAD TO
CONFIRM WHETHER IT WAS ONE
PERSON OR MORE.
AT THIS POINT WE KNOW OF THE ONE
PERSON, BUT THEY'RE NOT GOING TO
END THEIR INVESTIGATION WITH
THAT.
THEY'RE GOING TO CONTINUEBEEN S
ACTIVITY ALL ALONG SURROUNDING
THAT.
TO ANSWER MANY QUESTIONS, THEY
SET UP A SPACE NEAR THE SCHOOL
WHERE THE GOVERNOR AND OTHER LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS ARE
EXPECTED TO BRIEF REPORTERS WHEN
THEY HAVE ENOUGH INFORMATION I
GUESS THAT THEY CAN REALLY GIVE
US SOMETHING TO GO ON.
AS WE STATED ALL MORNING AND
AFTERNOON LONG, THE INFORMATION
COMES IN AND IT GETS UPDATED AND
CHANGES AS THMORE CLARITY COMESO
WHAT OCCURRED IN THIS HOUR FIING
SITUATION.
>> WE SHOULD TELL YOU THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS BEEN BRIEFED
NOT ONLY BY HOMELAND SECURITY
BUT ALSO BY FBI DIRECTOR BOB
MULLER AND THE PRESIDENT HAS
ALSO SPOKEN WITH CONNECTICUT
GOVERNOR DANA MALLOY TO DISCUSS
THE INCIDENT.
ALSO EXPRESS HIS CONDOLENCES.
WE ARE WAITING FOR THE GOVERNOR
AS WELL AS STATE POLICE TO HOLD
A NEWS CONFERENCE, WHICH IS
EXPECTED TO HAPPEN.
IT WAS SUPPOSED TO HAPPEN AROUND
1:00 THIS AFTERNOON, BUT
OBVIOUSLY THEY'RE CONTINUING TO
TRY AND GATHER MORE INFORMATION
ON THIS.
WE WANT TO GO RIGHT NOW TO
EYEWITNESS NEWS REPORTER MARCUS
SOLIS.
HE'S OUTSIDE THE FIREHOUSE WHERE
MANY PARENTS ARE GOING TO PICK
UP THEIR CHILDREN.
MARCUS, WHAT'S THE LATE HEEST
FROM THERE RIGHT NOW?
>> Reporter: WELL, LIZ, WE'RE AT
WASHINGTON AVENUE HERE.
THIS IS THE FINAL POINT WHERE
PARENTS CAN COME TO.
THEY HAVE TO WALK UP TO THAT
HILL TO GET UP TO THE FIREHOUSE
AND PICK UP THEIR CHILDREN.
SO MANY PEOPLE ARE DITCHING
THEIR CARS AND GOING UP THERE.
CERTAINLY LESS NOW.
WE KNOW THAT THERE ARE SEVERAL
PARENTS WHO ARE STILL AWAITING
WORD THAT CHILDREN ARE
UNACCOUNTED FOR.
WE SEE SOME MAKING IT BACK DOWN
THE HILL WITH THEIR CHILDREN
CERTAINLY RELIEVED AFTER WHAT'S
BEEN AN INCREDIBLY EMOTIONAL
MORNING.
WE JUST SPOKE WITH A PARENT AND
HIS FOURTH GRADE SON WHO
DESCRIBES SOME OF THE CHAOS THAT
WAS GOING ON INSIDE OF THAT
SCHOOL ON LOCKDOWN AND POLICE
WERE TRYING TO APPREHEND THE
SHOOTER AND BRING THIS TO AN
END.
LET'S HEAR A LITTLE BIT OF WHAT
THEY HAD TO SAY.
>> I WAS IN THE GYM AT THE TIME.
SO THE TEACHERS -- HE WE HEARD
LOTS OF BANGS, AND WE THOUGHT
THAT IT WAS THE CUSTODIAN
KNOCKING STUFF DOWN.
WE HEARD SCREAMING.
AND SO WENT ONTO -- WE WENT TO
THE WALL, AND WE SAT DOWN.
THEN THE POLICE CAME IN.
IT'S LIKE, IS HE IN HERE?
THEN HE RAN OUT.
THEN SOMEBODY YELLED GET TO A
SAFE PLACE, SO WE WENT TO THE
CLOSET IN THE GYM AND WE SAT
THERE FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
THEN THE POLICE LIKE WERE
KNOCKING ON THE DOOR, AND
THEY'RE LIKE, WE'RE EVACUATING
PEOPLE, WE'RE EVACUATING PEOPLE.
WE RAN OUT.
THEY'RE POLICE AT EVERY DOOR
LEADING US DOWN THIS WAY, THIS
WAY.
QUICK, QUICK, COME ON.
WE RAN DOWN TO THE FIREHOUSE.
THERE'S A MAN THAT PINNED DOWN
TO THE GROUND WITH HANDCUFFS ON,
AND WE THOUGHT THAT WAS THE
VICTIM.
>> ONE OF THE EYEWITNESSES
THERE, JUST A LITTLE BOY
DESCRIBING WHAT HE HEARD AND SAW
DURING THE SHOOTING.
I WANT TO GO TO ANOTHER
AFFILIATE FOR MORE.
>> MY SON WAS IN THE GYM WHEN IT
HAPPENED.
HE HEARD THE GUNSHOTS.
IT'S GOING TO BE ONE OF THOSE
THINGS WHEN THEY'RE TRYING TO
UNDERSTAND WHAT HAPPENED.
WHEN WE TELL THEM WHAT HAPPENED
IN DETAIL, IT'S GOING TO MAKE IT
MUCH WORSE.
>> DID THEY GIVE YOU ANY
INFORMATION?
WAS IT AN ADULT?
>> I DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
OUTSIDE OF THAT.
I HAVEN'T HAD ANY INFORMATION
OTHER THAN WHAT PEOPLE ARE
SPECULATING.
WE'RE GATHERING AROUND HERE.
>> LISTENING TO PARENTS AFTER
PARENTS AS THEY TELL THE TALE OF
WHAT THEIR CHILDREN HAD BEEN
THROUGH THAT MORNING AFTER
WITNESSING AN UNIMAGINABLE
TRAGEDY IN A QUAINT TOWN.
THIS IS NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE LOOKING AT THE PARENTS WHO
ARE BRINGING THEIR CHILDREN HOME
THROUGHOUT THE MORNING THIS HAS
BEEN HAPPENING AND AFTERNOON AS
WELL.
A NUMBER OF PARENTS ARE STILL
GOING TO THIS FIREHOUSE THAT
WE'RE LOOKING AT.
THEIR CHILDREN ARE THERE.
HUNDREDS WERE EVACUATED TO THAT
FACILITY.
>> ACTUALLY, WE JUST SAW THAT
GENTLEMAN THAT HAD BEEN SPOKEN
TO EARLIER STANDING THERE WITH
WITH THE GREEN SHIRT AND THE
WHILE BASEBALL CAP.
YOU CAN SEE THE PROXIMITY NOW
FROM THERE THROUGH THE WOODS
OVER HERE TO THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
THAT'S THE PATH THAT THE
CHILDREN TOOK FROM THE SCHOOL
THE TO THE FIREHOUSE WHEN THEY
TOOK COVER.
YOU JUST LOOK THE AT THOSE
PARENTS WHEN WE WERE LOOKING
OVER AT THE FIREHOUSE AND ELM
PRASING THEIR CHILDREN.
NOT SURE AT THAT MOMENT IF THEY
REALIZED HOW LUCKY THEY WERE
THAT THEY WERE STILL ABLE TO
HOLD ONIT TO THEIR CHILDREN
AFTER WHAT TRANSPIRED HERE.
>> THE SHOOTER AS OPPOSED TO --
THE INFORMATION WE HAVE IN
REGARD TO THE SHOOTER, 20 YEARS
OLD.
KILLED.
APPARENTLY HAD TWO GUNS, AND
WITH TIES TO THE SCHOOL.
NOT SURE WHAT THOSE TIES ARE.
WHETHER THEY HAVE CHILDREN AT
THE SCHOOL OR WENT TO THAT
SCHOOL, BUT WE ARE AWAITING THE
DETAILS IN REGARDS TO THAT
SHOOTER.
THE SECOND PERSON TAKEN INTO
CUSTODY, A MAN WEARING A BLACK
JACKET AND CAMOUFLAGE PANTS
ESCORTED OUT OF THE WOODS BY
POLICE PERSONNEL AND HANDCUFFED
AND TAKEN TO THE POLICE STATION
POSSIBLY WITH CHARGES AGAINST
THAT PERSON.
WE'RE AWAITING WORD.
>> YES, WE ARE.
WE'RE ALSO AWAITING LOU YOUNG.
WE'RE GOING TO TALK TO HIM RIGHT
NOW.
HE HAS BEEN ON THE SCENE, AND
WE'LL SEE WHAT HE HAS, WHAT HE'S
GATHERED SINCE WE LAST TALKED TO
HIM.
LOU.
>> ROB, WE'RE HERE ON RIVERSIDE
DRIVE HE LEADING UP TO THE
SCHOOL.
YOU SEE FOLKS COME BEING BACK
HERE, AND NOW THE FACES OF THE
PEOPLE COMING BACK.
EARLY ON THEY WERE FILLED WITH
RELIEF BECAUSE THEY REALIZED
THAT THEIR LOVED ONES HAD MADE
IT THROUGH THIS HORROR, BUT NOW
THE DEPTH OF THE TRAGEDY JUST
BEING THERE IN PROXIMITY TO IT
IS AFFECTING THEM.
WE'VE SEEN SOME VERY, VERY
GRIEF-STRICKEN AND AFFECTED AND
TEAR-STREAKED FACES DOWN THE
ROAD HERE.
I SPOKE WITH MAUREEN CARE HE
RINZ WHO WAS A NURSE AT DANBURY
HOSPITAL WHO RUSHED TO THE SCENE
WHEN SHE HEARD ABOUT THE
SHOOTING.
HE SHE ARRIVED WHEN THE LIGHTLY
INJURED PEOPLE WERE REMOVED AND
WANT UPPED TO DO SO IF THEY
COULD HELP OTHERS.
THERE WERE 20 CHILDREN INSIDE
THAT SHE WAS NOT ABLE TO HELP.
ALL OF THEM DEAD, AND SHE
DESCRIBES BEING PRESENT WHEN THE
PARENTS WERE GIVEN THE AWFUL
NEWS.
SHE IS JUST SHATTERED.
LISTEN.
>> Reporter: I SEE YOU'VE BEEN
CRYING.
>> YES.
>> Reporter: IS IT BECAUSE OF
WHAT YOU SAW?
>> NO, THEY WOULDN'T LET US IN
THE BUILDING.
ONE OF THE COPS, YOU KNOW, THE
WORSE THING HE'D SEEN IN HIS
ENTIRE CAREER, BUT IT WAS WHEN
THEY TOLD ALL THESE PARENTS
WAITING FOR CHILDREN TO COME
OUT.
THEY THOUGHT THAT THEY WERE, YOU
KNOW, STILL ALIVE.
THERE'S 20 PARENTS THAT WERE
JUST TOLD THAT THEIR CHILDREN
ARE DEAD.
IT WAS AWFUL.
>> YOU WERE UNABLE TO DO
ANYTHING?
>> RIGHT.
WE KNEW AT ONE POINT THEY ASKED
THE AMBULANCES TO LEAVE, THAT
THEY DIDN'T NEED THEM, AND WE
KNEW THAT THAT WASN'T A GOOD
SIGN.
>> Reporter: SHE WAS CRYING.
HER TEENAGE SON WAS ALSO CRYING,
JUST HAVING WITNESSED THAT
OUTPOURING OF GRIEF AND
DISBELIEF, THE PARENTS HEARING
THEIR WORST NIGHTMARES COME
TRUE, THAT THEIR CHILDREN HAD
BEEN KILLED.
THE LATEST NUMBERS FROM CBS
NEWS, 26 DEAD TOTAL, 18 OF THEM
CHILDREN.
A SHORT TIME AGO I'M TOLD THAT
POLICE FOUND TWO ADULTS ALIVE IN
THE SCHOOL HIDE INNINGING IN A .
THEY STAYED HIDDEN AND DID NOT
MOVE AND POLICE FOUND THEM IN
THE LAST HOUR OR SO.
THAT IS A SITUATION HERE THAT
HOW DESPERATE THE SITUATION WAS.
PEOPLE HID.
PEOPLE TRIED TO SAVE THEMSELVES.
PEOPLE WERE SAVED.
PEOPLE WITNESSED TERRIBLE
TRAGEDY AND TERRIBLE LOSS.
THIS IS GOING TO BE WITH THIS
COMMUNITY FOR A VERY LONG TIME.
WE'RE LIVE NIN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> HAVE YOU HEARD ANYTHING ABOUT
A SECOND SUSPECT BEING TAKEN
INTO CUSTODY IN THE WOODS JUST
AWAY FROM THE SCHOOL THERE
SHORTLY AFTER THE INCIDENT?
>> WHAT DID YOU HEAR?
HOW DID YOU FIRST HEAR ABOUT IT?
>> I GOT A -- THEY HAVE A --
IT'S AN ALERT THROUGH THE
SCHOOL.
YOUR PARENTS SIGN UP FOR IT.
I JUST GOT A MESSAGE SAYING FROM
THE SUPERINTENDENT THAT THERE
WAS UP AN UNCONFIRMED SHOOTING
AND EVERYBODY IS IN LOCKDOWN.
>> WHAT DID YOU THINK?
>> I WAS LIKE, OH, MY GOSH.
THEN I HAD NO IDEA THAT IT WAS
HER SCHOOL.
I'M LIKE -- IT JUST SEEMED SO
UNREAL.
MY HEART IS IN A MILLION PIECES
RIGHT NOW FOR PARENTS AND THE
CHILDREN AND FOR EVERYBODY
BECAUSE IT'S -- WHO WOULD EVER
THINK IN A SMALL TOWN AND
PEOPLE -- YOU KNOW, I MEAN, THE
SCHOOL IS LOCKED.
>> WE'RE GOING TO AFFILIATE WCBS
FOR MORE INFORMATION, WHAT
THEY'RE LEARNING ON THE GROUND
AS WELL.
LET'S LISTEN IN.
>> THAT IS WHAT THAT WOMAN WAS
GOING THROUGH.
SHE SHOWED UP READY TO DO HER
JOB, BUT THERE WAS NOTHING SHE
COULD DO.
THE PEOPLE THAT WERE ABLE TO BE
HELPED REMOVED FROM THE SCENE.
SHE WATCHED IN HORROR AND IS
GOING HOME TO TRY AND PROCESS
THAT.
>> YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT, LOU.
YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
THAT IS THE WORST THING THAT CAN
HAPPEN WHEN YOU SET UP THE
TRIAGE TO DO THE FIRST AID, AND
IT'S SIMPLY HE BEYOND THAT.
WE HAVE SEEN IT.
>> LOU, WE UNDERSTAND THAT THERE
IS GRIEF COUNSELORS -- THERE ARE
GRIEF COUNSELORS AT THAT
FIREHOUSE NOW TO DEAL WITH THIS
UNIMAGINABLE TRAGEDY.
>> Reporter: YEAH.
I MEAN, I'LL ALWAYS HEAR THAT
GRIEF COUNSELORS.
I'M NOT SURE WHAT YOU CAN SAY TO
A PARENT IN A SITUATION LIKE
THAT.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THAT'S LIKE.
I HOPE I NEVER HAVE TO FIND OUT
FIRSTHAND, BUT THERE ARE
PROFESSIONALS WHO ARE STANDING
BY TRYING TO WALK THESE PEOPLE
THROUGH THE INITIAL PROCESSES OF
THIS CRUSHING GRIEF THAT THEY
MUST BE FEELING, AND ESPECIALLY
AT THIS TIME OF YEAR, ESPECIALLY
CHILDREN, ESPECIALLY THE
LOCATION, THE INCON GRUTS OF IT
ALL IS STAGGERING.
>> LOU YOUNG, THANKS SO MUCH.
MYSTERY, MYSTERY, WHO IS THIS
20-SOMETHING-YEAR-OLD PEARL WITH
TIES TO THE SCHOOL WHO WOULD
PERPETRATE SUCH AN ACT.
>> THE NUMBERS CBS NEWS HAS
CONFIRMED, AT LEAST 26 ARE DEAD,
AT LEAST 18 OF THEM ARE
CHILDREN.
WE'RE HEARING OF THOSE PARENTS
WHO WENT TO REUNITE WITH THEIR
CHILDREN AT THE FIREHOUSE AND
WERE TOLD THEIR CHILDREN WERE
KILLED.
20 PARENTS WERE AT THE FIREHOUSE
TO GET THAT INFORMATION, 18
CHILDREN KILLED, MOTHERS,
FATHERS THERE.
WE SAW SO MANY REUNITE, EMBRACE
AS THEIR CHILDREN RAN TO THEM AS
WE LOOK AT VIDEO FROM EARLIER AS
PARENTS WERE TAKING THEIR
CHILDREN AWAY FROM THE
FIREHOUSE.
THEY HAD BEEN EVACUATED FROM THE
SCHOOL UNDER STATE POLICE
PROTECTION AFTER THOSE GUNSHOTS
WERE FIRED JUST AFTER 9:30 THIS
MORNING.
WE'RE LOOKING AT PICTURES OF
PARENTS AND THEIR CHILDREN AS
THEY ARE HEADED HOME.
MAYBE SOME OF THEM NOT KNOWING
THE SEVERITY OF THE SITUATION.
OTHERS KNOWING THIS.
THIS WAS A LITTLE EARLIER ON THE
SCENE JUST OUTSIDE THE
FIREHOUSE.
SO THE LATEST INFORMATION WE
HAVE IN REGARD TO THOSE INVOLVED
WITH THIS SHOOTING.
WE HAVE A 20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER
THAT WE KNOW DIED AT THE SCENE,
AND A SECOND SUSPECT IS IN
CUSTODY.
NOT SURE OF THE INVOLVEMENT WITH
THE SHOOTING, BUT WE ALSO GOT
WORD THAT A MAN DID COME OUT OF
THE WOODS IN HANDCUFFED ESCORTED
BY POLICE WEARING CAMOUFLAGE AND
LOOKING INTO ONE PARENT'S EYES
AND SAID I DID NOT DO IT.
THAT PERSON IS AT A POLICE
STATION BEING QUESTIONED AT THIS
HOUSE AND POSSIBLY FACING
CHARGES.
>> THAT WAS ACCORDING TO A
WITNESS ON THE SCENE WHO
ACTUALLY SAW THE POLICE, HE
SAYS, TAKING THIS PERSON OUT AND
CLAIMING HIS INNOCENCE,
PROFESSING HIS INNOCENCE.
>> TWO SEMI-AUTOMATIC HANDGUNS
WERE RETRIEVED FROM THE SCENE.
WE HEARD FROM SOME WITNESSES
THAT SAID THAT THEY HEARD DOZENS
OF ROUNDS, POSSIBLY 100 ROUNDS
BEING FIRED INSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
THERE ARE SEVERAL BUILDINGS
INSIDE THAT SCHOOL, SOME
CHILDREN WERE IN THE GYM.
THEY COULD HEAR THE GUNFIRE.
OTHERS WERE IN THEIR CLASSROOMS,
AND WE HEARD A STORY OF TWO
YOUNG GIRLS, POSSIBLY FIRST
GRADERS, WHO SAW THE GUNMAN GO
INTO THEIR CLASSROOM AND SHOOT
THEIR TEACHER.
>> STAY TUNED FOR THE VERY
LATEST.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON, EVERYONE.
MY NAME IS ROY OCCHIOGROSSO.
I WORK FOR GOVERNOR MALLOY.
AS YOU CAN IMAGINE, THE GOVERNOR
IS HORRIFIED BY WHAT'S HAPPENED.
HE IS MEETING WITH THE FAMILIES
RIGHT NOW.
HIS CHIEF CONCERN IS TO GET THE
FAMILIES THE INFORMATION THEY
NEED AS QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE.
THAT'S WHY HE'S NOT HERE.
I'M GOING TO INTRODUCE
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE FROM THE
STATE POLICE WHO WILL TALK A
LITTLE BIT ABOUT WHAT'S KNOWN SO
FAR.
WE UNDERSTAND YOU ARE ALL
INTERESTED IN INFORMATION.
WE'D LIKE TO GET YOU THAT
INFORMATION AS QUICKLY AS
POSSIBLE, BUT THE GOVERNOR'S
CHIEF CONCERN IS MAKING SURE
THAT THE FAMILIES HAVE
INFORMATION AS QUICKLY AS
POSSIBLE AND THAT'S WHY HE IS
NOW.
THIS IS LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE
FROM THE STATE POLICE.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON.
I WILL GIVE YOU SOME VERY BASIC
AND BRIEF INFORMATION AS WE KNOW
IT NOW.
WE WILL SET UP REGULAR PRESS
BRIEFINGS AS APPROPRIATE.
JUST AFTER 9:30 THIS MORNING
NEWTOWN POLICE RECEIVED A 911
CALL FOR AN EMERGENCY AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
NEWTOWN PD UPON OBTAINING
INFORMATION AS TO THE SITUATI
CONTACTED TO THE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE AND REQUESTED
ASSISTANCE.
ON AND OFF DUTY TROOPERS
RESPONDED TO THE SCHOOL, AND
REQUEST NEWTOWN POLICE
IMMEDIATELY UPON ARRIVAL ENTERED
THE SCHOOL AND BEGAN A COMPLETE
ACTIVE SHOOTER'S SEARCH OF THE
BUILDING.
THAT INCLUDED CHECKING EVERY
DOOR, EVERY CRACK, EVERY
CREVICE, EVERY PORTION OF THE
SCHOOL.
OUR MAIN OBJECTIVE WAS TO
EVACUATE AS QUICKLY AND
EFFICIENTLY AS POSSIBLE ANY AND
ALL STUDENTS AND FACULTY IN THE
SCHOOL.
THE ENTIRE SCHOOL WAS SEARCHED.
THAT WAS ACCOMPLISHED.
A STAGING AREA WAS SET UP.
THE STUDENT AND STAFF WERE PUT
INTO THAT STAGING AREA, AND SOON
THEREAFTER THE CHILDREN AND
STAFF WERE REUNITED WITH PARENTS
AND LOVED ONES.
THERE WERE SEVERAL FATALITIES AT
THE SCENE, BOTH STUDENTS AND
STAFF.
THERE'S NO INFORMATION RELATIVE
TO THAT THAT'S BEING RELEASED AT
THIS TIME UNTIL WE HAVE MADE
COMPLETE AND PROPER
NOTIFICATION.
THE SHOOTER IS DECEASED INSIDE
THE BUILDING.
THERE'S A GREAT DEAL OF WORK
THAT IS UNDERTAKEN IMMEDIATELY
UPON LOCATING THE SHOOTER, AND
THAT IS THERE'S A GREAT DEAL OF
SEARCH WARRANT ACTIVITY, THERE'S
A GREAT DEAL OF LAW ENFORCEMENT
ACTIVITY BOTH IN AND OUT OF
STATE TO ENSURE WE COVER ALL THE
BASES RELATIVE TO THAT SPECIFIC
INDIVIDUAL.
SUFFICE IT TO SAY THE SCENE IS
SECURE.
THE STATE POLICE MAJOR CRIME
SQUAD AND NEWTOWN POLICE
DEPARTMENT, DANBURY STATE'S
ATTORNEY AND MANY AGENCIES ARE
WORKING TOGETHER TO ANSWER ALL
THE QUESTIONS SURROUNDING
EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED.
WE WILL KEEP YOU BRIEFED AND
INFORMED ON A REGULAR BASIS AND
PUT EVERYTHING OUT VIA OUR
WEBSITE WITH THESE PRESS
CONFERENCES.
I'LL TURN IT BACK OVER TO HIM
RIGHT NOW.
>> THE GOVERNOR TOOK A CALL FROM
PRESIDENT OBAMA A LITTLE WHILE
AGO WHO WAS CALMISIN CALLING TO
HIS CONDOLENCES AND ON BEHALF OF
THE NATION AND TO ASSIST THE
FAMILIES AND ASSIST IN THE
INVESTIGATION.
WE WILL GET YOU INFORMATION AS
SOON AS WE CAN GET THE FAMILIES
THE INFORMATION.
THAT'S WHERE THE GOVERNOR IS.
AT SOME POINT LATER TODAY THE
GOVERNOR WILL BE HERE, AND WE
WILL SET UP REGULAR BRIEFINGS.
THANK YOU.
>> JUST GETTING THE VERY LATEST
UPDATE THERE.
A WORD FROM LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE AS WELL AS ROADWAY
OCHOGROSSI.
HE'S A SPOKEMAN FOR THE GOVERNOR
OFFICE.
>> WE'LL COME BACK FOR ANOTHER
BRIEFING AS QUICKLY AS WE CAN.
>> Reporter: YOU CAN SAY THE
PUBLIC IS NOT IN DANGER?
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
>> Reporter: EVERYTHING HERE,
ALL THE BRIEFINGS HERE?
>> RIGHT HERE.
>> A FINAL WORD.
THE PUBLIC IS NOT IN DANGER,
THAT THE SITE HAS BEEN SECURED.
WE WANT TO GO OVER JUST SOME OF
THE THINGS WE HAVE LEARNED.
NOT A LOT OF DETAIL HERE.
CERTAINLY THERE ARE VARIOUS AND
MIXED CONFLICTING REPORTS ON THE
NUMBER OF FATALITIES FROM
VARIOUS NETWORKS.
CNN CAN ONLY CONFIRM THAT AS
MANY AS 20 PEOPLE HAVE BEEN
KILLED IN THIS SCHOOL SHOOTING.
OF THOSE -- OKAY.
I'VE GOT A CNN PRODUCER ON THE
PHONE I'M TOLD WITH SOME
INFORMATION.
DAVID, WHAT CAN YOU TELL US?
>> HI, SUZANNE.
I'M RIGHT OUT IN FRONT OF THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL RIGHT NOW.
THIS WOODED AREAS THAT BASICALLY
SURROUNDS THE SCHOOL, AND
PARENTS ARE WALKING IN AND OUT
OF THIS FIREHOUSE USED AS A
MAKESHIFT SHELTER IN WHICH
THEY'RE TENDING THOSE INJURED
AND USHERING THOSE AWAY BY WAY
OF AMBULANCES.
THERE'S ABOUT FOUR AMBULANCES ON
THE SCENE HERE.
I'VE SPOKEN TO A NUMBER OF THE
PARENTS, AND APPARENTLY WHAT
TRANSPIRED WAS THAT EARLIER THIS
MORNING MANY OF THEM RECEIVED AN
AUTOMATED SCHOOL FROM THE SCHOOL
SUPERINTENDENT INDICATING THERE
WAS A SHOOTING.
IT WASN'T CLEAR WHICH SCHOOL AT
THAT POINT SHOOTING OCCURRED, SO
MANY OF THEM PANIC STRICKEN RAN
TO THEIR NEAREST SCHOOLS WHERE
SOME OF THE LOVED ONES ARE HELD.
SEVERAL HAVE SINCE NOW AUEMERGE.
SOME ARE ALMOST INCONSOLABLE HOW
UPSET THEY WERE.
ONE WOMAN CAME WALKING UP THE
STREET SCREAMING WHY, WHY?
NOT INDICATING WHAT HAPPENED.
OTHERS WERE CLUTCHING THEIR
CHILDREN AND TAKING THEM AWAY
FROM THE SCHOOL AS FAST AS THEY
COULD.
THAT'S THE SCENE HERE.
ONE OF HEAVY SECURITY.
WE'VE GOT ATF, FBI, SEVERAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICERS THAT ARE
BASICALLY CLAD IN TACTICAL GEAR
WITH WEAPONS DRAWN AND WIELDING
ASSAULT RIFLES AND ALL THE WHILE
YOU HAVE PARENTS STREAMING IN
AND OUT OF THIS AREA CLUTCHING
THEIR CHILDREN AND BASICALLY
JUST TRYING TO GET AWAY FROM THE
SCENE.
IT'S A MEDIA CIRCUS IN WHICH
MANY OF THE REPORTERS HERE
TRYING TO GET A SENSE OF WHAT
HAS HAPPENED.
BUT MOST PARENTS ARE JUST
ESSENTIALLY LOOKING TO GET AS
FAR AWAY FROM THE SCENE AS
POSSIBLE.
>> DPAIF
WE HEARD THAT THE GOVERNOR IS
MEETING WITH THE FAMILIES, THE
PARENTS OF THOSE WHOSE CHILDREN
HAVE BEEN KILLED.
HAVE YOU GOTTEN A SENSE OF WHERE
THE GOVERNOR, WHERE THOSE PAR  T
PARENTS ARE ON THE SCENE WHERE
YOU ARE AND WHETHER OR NOT
YOU'VE SEEN SOME PARENTS WHO
HAVE RECEIVED THE DEVASTATING
NEWS?
>> Reporter: WE HAVE.
MOST OF THE PARENTS THAT ARE
STRICKEN WITH SOME OF THAT
DEVASTATING NEWS, THAT MORE
FATAL NEWS ARE HOLED UP IN THAT
FIREHOUSE.
THERE ARE AT LEAST SEVERAL DOZEN
PEOPLE INSIDE, SEVERAL PARENTS.
ON OCCASION YOU'LL SEE PEOPLE
COMING OUT AND SORT OF ALMOST
INCONSOLABLE AS I MENTIONED
BEFORE.
IT SEEMS THAT THAT FIREHOUSE
CONTINUES TO BE SORT OF THE
SAFEHOUSE AS AUTHORITIES IN THE
REGION REALLY START TO TRY TO
PIN DOWN THIS AREA.
WELL, IT DOESN'T SEEM TO BE AS
ACTIVE A SCENE AS IT DID
EARLIER.
THEY'RE STILL GOING HOUSE TO
HOUSE, STILL CHECKING BUILDINGS.
IT'S NOT CLEAR THIS IS AN
ENTIRELY SECURE SCENE.
THAT SAID YOU HAVE PARENTS LIKE
I MENTIONED BEFORE REALLY TRYING
TO GET AS FAR AWAY AS POSSIBLE.
>> DAVID, WHAT ARE THOSE PARENTS
SAYING.
THEY WERE ALERTED THERE WAS A
SHOOTING THAT TOOK PLACE.
ARE THESE PARENTS SATISFIED THAT
THEY GOT INFORMATION IN A TIMELY
WAY?
ARE THEY DESPONDENT OR CONFUSED?
>> I THINK YOU HIT IT ON THE
HEAD THERE.
DESPONDENT WOULD BE THE
OPERATIVE WORD RIGHT NOW.
IT'S CLEARLY ONE OF A PARENT'S
MOST FEARED PROSPECTS HERE, OF
GETTING NEWS OF THIS SORT,
PARTICULARLY WHILE THEY'RE AT
WORK, THAT THEIR CHILDREN ARE IN
HARM'S WAY.
MOST OF THE PARENTS, THE FEW
THAT WE ACTUALLY GOT A CHANCE TO
SPEAK TO, WERE JUST RELIEVED
THAT THEIR CHILDREN WERE ALL
RIGHT.
THE RESOUNDING FEELING THAT ONE
REALLY GETS FROM BEING DOWN HERE
IS SORT OF A SENSE OF NOT
KNOWING WHAT TRANSPIRED AND WHAT
MAY CONTINUE TO BE TRANSPIRING.
IT'S NOT CLEAR THIS IS AN
ENTIRELY SECURE SCENE.
AT THE SAME TIME IT'S ONE OF
THOSE THINGS THAT IT REALLY,
REALLY CAN'T BE PUT INTO WORDS
HOW TERRIBLE THIS MUST BE FOR
SOME FAMILY MEMBERS.
SO AS THEIR SORT OF WIPING TEARS
AWAY FROM THEIR EYES TALKING
INTO CELL PHONES WITH FAMILY
MEMBERS AND FRIENDS RECANTING A
SEEN THEY WITNESSED INSIDE THE
FIREHOUSE AND TALKING WITH
CHILDREN WHO HAD TO BE HUDDLED
INTO CLASSROOMS AS ACCOMPLICE
AND TEACHERS HUDDLED THEM
TOWARDS THE BACK OF THE ROOM AS
THIS SHOOTING TOOK PLACE.
IT'S JUST -- IT'S A SCENE OF
SHOCK, DISMAY AND IT'S NOT CLEAR
WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN NEXT.
>> DAVID, IT'S KIND OF HARD
SOMETIMES TO GAUGE, YOU KNOW,
WHAT KIDS ARE GOING THROUGH AND
WHAT THEY'RE FEELING AT THE
TIME.
WE'VE SEEN SOME CHILDREN WHO
HAVE DESCRIBED WHAT THEY SAW.
WHAT DO YOU GET FROM SOME OF THE
CHILDREN WHO HAVE LEFT WITH
THEIR PARENTS?
>> Reporter: I TALKED TO ONE
PARENT WITH A CHILD.
FOR OBVIOUS REASONS THOSE
PARENTS DON'T WANT TO HAVE THEIR
CHILDREN SPEAKING PARTICULARLY
AFTER AN INCIDENT LIKE THIS, BUT
IN MANY OF THE -- IT SEEMS AT
LEAST FROM WHAT THIS CHILD WAS
SAYING THAT MANY OF THE CHILDREN
HERE DON'T REALLY HAVE A GOOD
SENSE OF WHAT TRANSPIRED TODAY.
IT WAS SCARY.
IT WAS FRIGHTENING FOR MANY OF
THEM.
AND THIS LITTLE GIRL I SPOKE TO
WAS SAYING THAT MANY, MANY
PEOPLE IN HER CLASSROOM WERE
CRYING AS THEY WERE HUDDLED INTO
THE BACK ROOM OF THIS SCHOOL
BUILDING.
SHE WAS IN A THIRD GRADE CLASS,
ACTUALLY, AS POLICE BARGED IN.
AND TEACHERS JUST TRIED TO IN A
SENSE GET A GOOD SENSE OF WHAT
WAS HAPPENING AND TRIED TO
PROTECT THEM.
WHAT IS CONFUSING FOR THEM, AND
PROBABLY UNDERSTANDABLY SO.
WHAT REALLY HAPPENS NEXT FOR
THEM, I'M SURE THE PARENTS ARE
GOING TO GO HOME AND TRY TO
EXPLAIN AS BEST THEY CAN.
YOU TALK TO PARENTS HERE AND
THEY REALLY SAY THEIR HEART GOES
OUT TO THOSE WHO MAY STILL BE
HOLED UP IN THE FIREHOUSE TRYING
TO COME TO TERMS WITH WHAT HAS
HAPPENED.
>> DAVID, THERE HAVE BEEN SO
MANY DIFFERENT REPORTS ABOUT HOW
MANY PEOPLE HAVE BEEN INJURED OR
KILLED.
I WOULD IMAGINE THAT WOULD BE
VERY, VERY US FROM TRALTI IFRUS
PEOPLE ON THE GROUND WHO JUST
DON'T UNDERSTAND THE MAGNITUDE,
THEY DON'T KNOW JUST HOW
SIGNIFICANT THIS IS.
IS THERE A SENSE THAT PEOPLE
JUST WANT MORE INFORMATION?
>> I THINK THAT'S THE DRIVING
THING HERE.
EVERYBODY IS LOOKING FOR MORE
INFORMATION.
YOU HAVE ALL THESE DIFFERENT
GROUPS WORKING TOGETHER, YOU
HAVE FBI THAT IS HERE, THE ATF,
STATE AND LOCAL POLICE.
AND YOU KNOW THERE IS A SENSE OF
TRYING TO GET A HANDLE ON THE
SITUATION.
AT THE SAME TIME, IT IS NOT
CLEAR WHO THIS PERSON WAS, IF
THERE WAS JUST ONE PERSON,
WHETHER THAT THERE IS STILL A
DANGER OUT THERE.
I UNDERSTAND THERE IS --
AUTHORITIES WILL BE HOLDING A
PRESS CONFERENCE IN SHORT ORDER
TO MAYBE ANSWER SOME OF THOSE
QUESTIONS.
BUT, YOU KNOW, A SCENE LIKE THIS
IS REALLY PROBABLY LEAVES MORE
UNANSWERED QUESTIONS THAN WE
COULD EVER GET.
HOW A SHOOTING COULD OCCUR
INSIDE AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IS
JUST -- YOU KNOW, IT IS JUST ONE
OF THOSE THINGS THAT -- YOU
COVER THESE STORIES, IT'S -- YOU
ARE ALWAYS LEFT WITH THOSE
QUESTIONS OF WHY THIS TOOK
PLACE.
AND THERE IS REALLY NO SENSE OF
ANSWERS THAT COULD REALLY EVER
SATISFY THAT QUESTION IT SEEMS.
BUT MANY PEOPLE HERE ON THE
GROUND, PARTICULARLY
AUTHORITIES, ARE TRYING TO
SECURE THE AREA, MAKE SURE THAT
THERE IS NOT ANOTHER INDIVIDUAL
AROUND, AND ESSENTIALLY WORK TO
CONSOLE THOSE FAMILY MEMBERS WHO
MAY HAVE LOST PEOPLE TODAY.
>> I KNOW IT'S HARD AND YOU
NEVER REALLY GET OVER THE KIND
OF SHOCK AND THE KIND OF EMOTION
THAT PEOPLE EXPERIENCE IN THIS
KIND OF EPISODE.
I COVERED COLUMBINE AND YOU
REALLY DON'T THINK THESE KINDS
OF THINGS WILL TAKE PLACE, AND
THEN THEY TAKE PLACE TIME AND
TIME AGAIN.
DAVID, REALLY QUICKLY IF YOU
CAN, PAINT A PICTURE IF YOU WILL
OF THE COMMUNITY, WHO ARE THEY,
WHAT ARE THEY LIKE.
>> WELL, THIS TOWN IS, I'D SAY,
PROBABLY AN HOUR'S DRIVE NORTH
OF NEW YORK CITY AND SORT OF A
SLEEPY NEW ENGLAND TOWN.
AND YOU HAVE, YOU KNOW, IT'S
REALLY PRETTY SUBURBAN TOWN IN
WHICH, YOU KNOW, TONIGHT'S
WOODED AREAS SURROUNDING THIS
SCHOOL, AND THE THING YOU HEAR
FROM PARENTS AND FROM COMMUNITY
MEMBERS IS THAT HOW COULD THIS
HAPPEN HERE?
HOW COULD THIS HAPPEN IN THIS
SLEEPY LITTLE TOWN WHERE, YOU
KNOW, IT'S FILLED WITH JUST SORT
OF THESE PICTURESQUE SCENES OF
WHAT YOU WOULD IMAGINE OF A NEW
ENGLAND TOWN, ANTIQUE SHOPS
ALONG ROADWAYS AND IRONICALLY A
CEMETERY, AN OLD CEMETERY DATING
BACK TO THE 1800s SITS ON A
ROADWAY OVERLOOKING --
OVERLOOKING THE SCHOOL ITSELF.
SO THE QUESTION OF WHY AND WHY
HERE IS OMNIPRESENT.
>> DAVID, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
REALLY APPRECIATE YOUR REPORTING
AND OBVIOUSLY YOU'VE BEEN
TALKING TO A LOT OF FAMILIES AND
IT IS JUST DEVASTATING FOR THAT
COMMUNITY AND FOR ALL OF US TO
SEE WHAT HAS TRAN SPISPIRED TOD.
MEREDITH ARTILY SPOKE WITH US
EARLIER AND SHE ACTUALLY TALKED
WITH A WITNESS WHO WAS INSIDE OF
THE SCHOOL.
>> SHE WAS IN A MEETING THIS
MORNING, SHE SAID AROUND 9:30,
9:35.
AND SHE -- THERE WERE ABOUT
SEVEN PEOPLE IN THE ROOM, AND IT
WAS A MEETING REGARDING ONE OF
HER KIDS, SHE HAS CHILDREN AT
THE SCHOOL.
AND SHE VOLUNTEERS AT THE SCHOOL
AS WELL.
AND SHE HEARD -- SHE DESCRIBED
IT AS A POP, POP, POP IN THE
HALL AND THEY ALL HEARD IT.
SEVEN PEOPLE IN MEETING ROOM.
THEY HEARD THAT SOUND IN THE
HALL.
AND THEY -- SHE SAID THREE
PEOPLE WENT OUT INTO THE HALL,
THE PRINCIPAL, THE VICE
PRINCIPAL AND THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST.
AND TO HEAR HER DESCRIBE IT, SHE
SAID THREE PEOPLE WENT OUT INTO
THE HALL AND ONLY ONE -- ONLY
ONE PERSON CAME BACK, WHICH WAS
THE VICE PRINCIPAL, SHE SAID,
WHO WAS SHOT IN THE LEG OR THE
FOOT WHO CAME CRAWLING BACK.
AND SHE SAID THAT SHE COWHERED
UNDER THE TABLE DURING THAT
MOMENT AND CALLED 911 AS DID THE
OTHER PEOPLE IN THE ROOM.
SHE SAID SHE NEVER SAW THE
SHOOTER, THAT SHE WAS, YOU KNOW,
SHE WAS UNDER THE TABLE, THAT
THE SHOOTING HAPPENED IN THE
HALLWAY, AND TO HEAR HER
DESCRIBE IT, SHE SAID THERE
WAS -- THERE MUST HAVE BEEN A
HUNDRED ROUNDS.
AND I ASKED HER TO CLARIFY THAT,
I SAID REALLY TRULY, A HUNDRED
ROUNDS AND SHE SAID AT LEAST.
>> WHEN THE VICE PRINCIPAL CAME
CRAWLING BACK, WHAT HAPPENED AT
THAT POINT?
WHAT DID SHE SAY?
HOW DID THE VICE PRINCIPAL
MANAGE TO MOVE OR ESCAPE, CAN
YOU -- DID SHE DESCRIBE WHAT WAS
THE SITUATION AS HE WAS CRAWLING
BACK?
>> SHE DESCRIBED -- SHE SAID
THAT -- SHE SAID THERE WAS
CONFUSION, THERE WAS YELLING AND
UNDERSTANDABLY, SHE SAID THERE
WAS YELLING IN THE HALLWAY, AND
SHE COULDN'T TELL FOR A WHILE IF
IT WAS THE POLICE OR THE
SHOOTER.
WHEN I TALKED TO HER, SHE WAS
STILL INSIDE THE SCHOOL, THE
SCHOOL IS ON LOCKDOWN.
SO SHE COULDN'T TELL -- SHE
DIDN'T KNOW IF THE SHOOTER WAS
DEAD YET OR STILL THERE.
>> WHAT DID THE VICE PRINCIPAL
LOOK LIKE WHEN SHE SAW HIM
RETURN?
>> I DIDN'T HEAR HER DESCRIBE
THAT.
SHE SAID, YOU KNOW, SHE SAID,
LISTEN, THIS IS A NICE TOWN,
THIS IS A NICE SCHOOL, THESE ARE
THE KIND OF THINGS THAT DON'T
HAPPEN THERE, SHE NOTED THIS WAS
NOT SOME HIGH POWERED MEETING,
IT WAS, YOU KNOW, ABOUT MY --
ABOUT ONE OF MY CHILDREN WHO WAS
IN SECOND GRADE THERE.
AND SHE, YOU KNOW, SHE WAS
TEARFUL.
JUST UNDERSTANDABLY PANICKED.
AND SHE SAID THEY MARCHED AT
SOME POINT, I DON'T HAVE THE
LENGTH OF TIME, BUT SHE SAID
SOME POINT AFTER THE SHOOTING
THEY MARCHED US OUT IN THE
HALLWAY, RIGHT PAST THE TWO
BODIES LAYING IN THE HALLWAY IN
A POOL OF BLOOD.
>> CNN HAS LEARNED AT LEAST 20
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN KILLED, TEN OF
THEM CHILDREN.
WANT TO BRING IN OUR JOHN KING
OUT OF WASHINGTON, WHO HAS MORE
INFORMATION.
JOHN, WHAT ARE YOU LEARNING?
>> Reporter: SUZANNE, I'VE BEEN
SPEAKING TO A FEDERAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIAL HERE IN
WASHINGTON WHO IS GETTING
INFORMATION DIRECTLY FROM THE
SCENE.
STATE POLICE ON THE SCENE, FBI
OFFICIALS ON THE SCENE, IN
CONNECTICUT, THIS SOURCE
CAUTIONING THAT AS YOU KNOW IN
THESE SITUATIONS THE NUMBERS
ALMOST ALWAYS CHANGE.
BUT THE OFFICIAL TELLS US HE'S
NOW SEEING CONSISTENT REPORTING
FROM THE SCENE THAT THERE ARE
MORE THAN 20 PHI TALLFATALITIES
ARE CHILDREN.
AND EXPECT THE NUMBERS TO
CHANGE, BUT HE IS NOW SEEING
CONSISTENT REPORTS OF THE DEATH
TOLL BEING CLOSER TO 30 THAN TO
20.
HE'S HEARING A NUMBER
CONSISTENT, HE SAYS 26, 27, BUT
DOESN'T TRUST THAT YET.
SAID HE BELIEVES THE NUMBER WILL
BE CLOSER TO 30 THAN 20.
ALSO SAYS THAT FROM REPORTING
FROM THE SCENE FROM LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS THERE,
BOTH STATE AND FEDERAL, SUZANNE,
THAT THE SHOOTER IS DEAD, WOULD
NOT GIVE ANY DETAILS ON HOW THE
SHOOTER WAS -- WHETHER THE
SHOOTER KILLED HIMSELF OR KILLED
BY POLICE AT THE SCENE BUT SAYS
THE SHOOTER HAS A DIRECT
CONNECTION TO THE SCHOOL, WOULD
NOT DESCRIBE FOR ME AT THIS
EARLY POINT OF THE INVESTIGATION
WHAT THAT CONNECTION IS.
>> SO HE WASN'T ABLE TO SAY
WHETHER OR NOT THAT CONNECTION
WAS A PARENT OR A -- OR AN
EMPLOYEE OF THE SCHOOL AT THE
TIME?
>> Reporter: HE KNOWS THAT
INFORMATION, HAS THAT
INFORMATION FROM THE SCENE, BUT
WAS NOT WILLING TO DISCUSS IT AT
THIS POINT, SAYS IT IS VERY
SENSITIVE AT THE MOMENT, WANTS
TO DEFER OF THE RELEASE OF THE
MOST SENSITIVE INFORMATION TO
THE AUTHORITIES ON THE SCENE,
BECAUSE, AS YOU KNOW, WE'RE
HEARING FROM OTHER
CORRESPONDENTS THAT THEY'RE
GOING TO HOUSES, KNOWN HOUSES,
FRIENDS, ASSOCIATES AND THE
LIKE, AS THE INVESTIGATION
UNFOLDS.
THERE ARE SOME THINGS THEY WANT
TO KEEP PRIVATE AT THE MOMENT.
>> LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE SAID HE
WAS ACTUALLY -- THEY DIDN'T GIVE
THE NUMBERS, THE FATALITY
NUMBERS THERE, STILL IN THE
PROCESS OF NOTIFYING SOME OF THE
FAMILIES.
YOUR AUTHORITIES ARE SAYING
THEY'RE NOT PUTTING OUT THOSE
EXACT NUMBERS UNTIL THEY GET A
REAL HANDLE ON BEING ABLE TO
REACH SOME OF THOSE PARENTS AND
LET THEM KNOW WHAT IS GOING ON.
>> Reporter: THAT'S EXACTLY
RIGHT.
THEY ALSO WANT TO GO THROUGH
EVERY LAST NOOK AND CRANNY OF
THE SCHOOL UNFORTUNATELY TO MAKE
SURE THAT THERE IS NO OTHER
FATALITIES INSIDE AND ALSO NO
OTHER PEOPLE WHO MIGHT BE HIDING
INSIDE.
AND THEY SAY THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT AND STATE POLICE ON
THE SCENE HAVE URGED EVERYONE
NOT TO GIVE A FIRM FATALITY
NUMBER JUST YET UNTIL THEY MAKE
SURE THAT ALL OF THE FAMILIES
HAVE BEEN SPECIFICALLY NOTIFIED.
AND ALL OF THE FAMILIES HAVE
RECEIVED OFFICIAL WORD.
BUT, AGAIN, T