20 LITTLE FLAGS DOT THE CURB
OUTSIDE THE HIGH SCHOOL.
TEDDY BEARS, ANGELS KEEPING
WATCH NEAR THE CENTER OF TOWN
AND THE TOWN'S FLAG IN THE
CENTRAL OF MAIN STREET AT HALF
STAFF.
>> THE ONCE JOYFUL CHRISTMAS
TREE HAS A DIFFERENT GLOW
SURROUNDED BY MEMORIAL CANDLES
AND THE LIGHTS OF THE WORLD'S
MEDIA.
THE RESIDENTS OF NEWTOWN KNOW IT
WILL TAKE TIME FOR THIS TOWN TO
HEAL BUT THEY ARE ALSO
DETERMINED TO SHOW THE WORLD
THAT NEWTOWN WILL NOT JUST
BECOME ANOTHER WORD FOR TRAGEDY.
>> THE TOWN RIGHT NOW IS
MOURNING.
WE'RE SAD.
I THINK DOWN THE ROAD WE'LL
DEFINITELY BE STRONGER.
WE HAVE TO BE STRONGER.
>>> TONIGHT, ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
AMERICANS ACROSS THE COUNTRY
STANDING UP AGAINST GUN
VIOLENCE.
>> THIS IS THE STRAW THAT BREAKS
THE CAMEL'S BACK.
PEOPLE HAVE TO RESPOND.
>> TO AN UNPRECEDENTED GATHERING
WE THOUGHT AND HOPED WOULD NEVER
BE REPEATED.
TEN FAMILIES FROM THE AURORA
SHOOTING, THEY'RE SPEAKING OUT
WITH SOLIDARITY.
PLUS, DR. ROSS TAKES US INSIDE
THE MIND OF A KILLER.
>> HE WAS DIFFERENT.
HE WAS QUIET.
A NICE KID, A GOOD KID.
>> HOW THIS TIME IT MAY BE
DIFFERENT IN CHANGING THE LAW OF
THE LINE.
>> WE CAN'T TOLERATE THIS
ANYMORE.
THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
AND TO END THEM, WE MUST CHANGE.
>> THIS IS "PIERS MORGAN
TONIGHT."
>> GOOD EVENING.
JUST A FEW MINUTES IN THE
STUDIO, WE'RE GOING TO DO
SOMETHING QUITE EXTRAORDINARY.
I'M GOING TO SIT DOWN WITH TEN
AMERICANS WHO LIVED WHAT WE
HOPED MIGHT BE THE LAST MASS
SHOOTING IN THIS COUNTRY, THE
MASSACRE IN A MOVIE HEATER IN
AURORA, COLORADO.
YOU NEED TO HEAR WHAT THESE
PEOPLE HAVE TO SAY ABOUT GUNS IN
AMERICA.
>>> BUT FIRST, A PICTURE NONE OF
US EVER IMAGINED OR FEARED WE
WOULD EVER HAVE TO SEE.
THE FIRST FUNERALS OF THE 20
YOUNG CHILDREN KILLED AT THE
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, ON FRIDAY.
6-YEAR-OLD JACK PINTO WAS LAID
TO REST TODAY.
IN HIS OBITUARY, HIS FAMILY
WROTE, "JACK WILL FOREVER BE
REMEMBERED FOR THE IMMEASURABLE
JOY HE BROUGHT TO ALL WHO HAD
THE PLEASURE OF KNOWING HIM, A
JOY WHOSE WIDE REACH BELIED HIS
SIX YEARS."
HE WAS BURIED IN THE JERSEY OF
HIS FAVORITE TEAM MEMBER OF THE
NEW YORK GIANTS.
HIS FAMILY SAID HE COULD GET
WHATEVER HE WANTED JUST BY
BATTING HIS LONG EYELASHES.
LISTEN NOW TO WHAT MAY BE ONE OF
THE MOST HEARTBREAKING OF ALL IN
THIS GHASTLY TRAGEDY.
PARENTS TALKING ABOUT THE MOMENT
THEY LEARNED THEIR DAUGHTER HAD
DIED IN THE CARNAGE AT SANDY
HOOK SCHOOL.
>> SHE WAS A BALL OF FIRE.
SHE RULED THE ROOST.
SHE --
>> OUR LITTLE CEO, WE CALLED
HER.
SHE WAS -- SHE WAS THE BOSS.
>> I GOT TO THE FIREHOUSE.
>> WE HAD NO IDEA AT THIS POINT.
WE THOUGHT OKAY, THE REPORTS ARE
THAT ONE OR TWO PEOPLE MAY HAVE
BEEN INJURED.
>> I WALKED AROUND THE
FIREHOUSE.
MAYBE SHE IS IN.
THIS MAYBE SHE IS THERE.
>> I MUST HAVE DONE 100 LAPS.
>> I KNOW EXACTLY WHAT SHE WAS
WEARING.
I WAS GOING TO SEE HER LITTLE
PONYTAIL COME AROUND THE CORNER
AND HER JACKET AND HER BLACK
GLITTERY UGGS THAT SHE HAD ON
THAT MORNING.
THEY FINALLY AROUND 1:15 ASKED
EVERYBODY TO SIT DOWN, AND THEY
SAID THAT IT WAS A TRAGIC DAY IN
NEWTOWN TODAY, AND 20 CHILDREN
WERE KILLED.
AND -- TELL ME THAT MY LITTLE
GIRL WAS GONE.
>> THERE WAS SO MUCH PAIN AND
CONFUSION WHEN THAT ANNOUNCEMENT
WAS MADE.
THE LIFE WAS JUST SUCKED OUT OF
EVERYONE IN THE ROOM.
AND, YOU KNOW, I JUST
POINT-BLANK FOUND A STATE
TROOPER AND ARE THERE ANY
SURVIVORS?
ARE YOU TELLING ME THAT STANDING
HERE AS A PARENT, MY CHILD IS
GONE?
AND HE SAID YES.
>> THE BED SHE HAD JUST GOTTEN
OUT OF.
AND WE JUST STAYED IN BED.
IT'S STILL NOT REAL THAT MY --
MY LITTLE GIRL WHO WAS SO FULL
OF LIFE AND WHO WANTS A HORSE SO
BADLY AND WHO IS GOING TO GET
COWGIRL BOOTS FOR CHRISTMAS
ISN'T COMING HOME.
>> SO MANY AWFUL, AWFUL ACCOUNTS
OF THIS APPALLING TRAGEDY.
WHAT WILL AMERICA DO ABOUT GUNS?
JOINING ME NOW IS SENATOR DIANNE
FEINSTEIN.
SHE IS INTRODUCING AN ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN WHEN CONGRESS
RECONVENES IN JANUARY.
IT'S ALMOST TOO MUCH TO BEAR,
ISN'T IT, LISTENING?
>> YES, IT IS.
IT'S VERY HARD.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT I WOULD DO IF
IT WERE MY DAUGHTER.
I JUST -- THIS IS SO BAD.
IT IS SO HORRIFIC.
YOU KNOW, ONE POINT YOU FEEL
THIS TERRIBLE GRIEF, AND THEN
YOU FEEL THIS ANGER THAT THIS
COULD HAPPEN IN OUR COUNTRY,
WHERE CHILDREN SHOULD BE AT
LEAST SAFE IN A SCHOOL.
ANYWAY, YES, I'M GOING TO DO AN
ASSAULT WEAPONS PIECE OF
LEGISLATION.
AND IT'S GOING TO BE STRONG, AND
IT'S GOING TO BE DEFINITIVE.
AND IT'S GOING TO BAN BY NAME AT
LEAST 100 MILITARY-STYLE
SEMIAUTOMATIC ASSAULT WEAPONS.
AND IT'S GOING TO BAN BIG CLIPS,
DRUMS OR STRIPS OF MORE THAN TEN
BULLETS.
AND IT'S THIS PARTICULAR
CATEGORY OF WEAPON WHICH THE
BUSHMASTER IS.
IT'S A KILLER WEAPON.
YOU CAN FIRE IT VERY QUICKLY.
IT HAS VERY LITTLE RECOIL, VERY
LITTLE KICK, AND IT'S VERY HIGH
VELOCITY.
AND IT DOESN'T BELONG ON THE
STREETS OF OUR CITY.
AND IT DOESN'T BELONG IN A PLACE
WHERE A 20-YEAR-OLD LIKE THIS
PARTICULAR 20-YEAR-OLD COULD GET
AHOLD OF IT AND GO IN AND DO
WHAT HE DID.
AND THIS MAKES ME VERY ANGRY.
>> WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THOSE WHO
SAY I HAVE MY SECOND AMENDMENT
RIGHTS.
I'M ENTITLED TO BEAR ARMS.
YOU ARE NOT ENTITLED TO TAKE
AWAY THAT RIGHT BY REMOVING
THESE KIND OF WEAPONS FROM THE
STREETS AND FROM THE STORES.
>> THERE IS NO SECOND AMENDMENT
RIGHT TO BEAR EVERY TYPE OF
WEAPON THAT YOU KNOW OF.
THESE ARE A CERTAIN CLASS OF
WEAPONS.
THEY ARE DESIGNED TO KILL LARGE
NUMBERS OF PEOPLE IN CLOSE
COMBAT.
I DON'T BELIEVE THE SECOND
AMENDMENT COVERS THEM.
THE SECOND AMENDMENT WAS WRITTEN
A LONG TIME BEFORE THESE -- THIS
CLASS OF WEAPONS WAS FOUNDED,
MERCHANDISED, AND SPREAD ALL
OVER OUR COUNTRY.
WHERE THEY FALL INTO THE HANDS
OF JUVENILES, GRIEVANCE KILLERS,
PEOPLE WHO GO INTO OUR MALLS,
OUR THEATERS, OUR STORES, OUR
BUSINESSES, AND NOW OUR SCHOOLS
AND JUST KILL PEOPLE FOR NO GOOD
REASON.
IT'S GOT TO STOP.
>> TELL ME ABOUT THE REACTION
YOU'VE HAD ALREADY FROM OTHER
POLITICIANS.
WE'VE BEEN TRYING TO GET ANY GUN
SUPPORTING POLITICIAN ON THE
SHOW.
AND LIKE MOST SHOWS ON AMERICAN
TELEVISION RIGHT NOW, THEY DON'T
WANT TO COME ON.
THEY'RE HIDING AWAY, AS ARE
MEMBERS OF THE NRA AND ALL THE
USUAL SUSPECTS WHEN THESE
TERRIBLE THINGS HAPPEN.
ARE YOU DETECTING, SENATOR, THAT
THERE IS CHANGE IN MOOD?
ARE YOU HOPING THIS IS A TIPPING
POINT?
>> YES, I HOPE SO, PIERS.
I HAD TO DO A BRIEF SEGMENT ON
"MEET THE PRESS" YESTERDAY
MORNING.
AND AFTERWARDS, I PROBABLY GOT
20 PHONE CALLS AT HOME HERE IN
WASHINGTON.
VERY UNUSUAL, PEOPLE FROM
WASHINGTON AND CALIFORNIA
CALLING AND SAYING WE WANT TO
HELP WITH THIS.
IT'S GOT TO STOP.
I EVEN HAD ONE MAN WHO WAS A
MEMBER OF THE NRA WHO SAID I
HAVE AN AR-15, AND I'M GOING TO
GET RID OF IT.
I'M A HUNTER, AND I WANT YOU TO
DO SOMETHING ABOUT THESE ASSAULT
WEAPONS.
SO I'M GOING TO DO MY LEVEL BEST
TO TRY.
I DID IT ONCE BEFORE IN 1993.
WE SAT DOWN AND WE WROTE A BILL,
AND THAT BILL PASSED THE SENATE.
CHUCK SCHUMER INTRODUCED IT IN
THE HOUSE.
IT PASSED.
IT WAS NOT AMENDED.
IT WAS PASSED.
AND IT WENT TO THE PRESIDENT.
PRESIDENT CLINTON SIGNED IT, AND
IT WAS THE LAW FOR TEN YEARS.
AND OVER TIME, IT BEGAN TO WIND
DOWN THE SUPPLY OF THESE
WEAPONS.
AND PARTICULARLY THE CLIPS,
DRUMS, OR STRIPS OF OVER 100
BULLETS.
I MEAN, YOU HAVE TO REALIZE THE
PERSON THAT WENT INTO THAT
HEATER IN AURORA HAD A DRUM WITH
100 BULLETS IN HIS ASSAULT
WEAPON.
FORTUNATELY, THAT DRUM JAMMED OR
ELSE HE WOULD HAVE HAD 100 CLEAR
SHOTS AT PEOPLE SITTING IN SEATS
IN A MOVIE THEATER.
NOW, HERE YOU PROBABLY HAD THIS
MAN FIRE MORE THAN 100 BULLETS.
I MEAN, WE'VE JUST HEARD WHERE
NO CHILD HAD LESS THAN THREE
BULLETS IN THEM OF WHAT IS A
KILLER WEAPON THAT SHOULDN'T BE
ON THE STREETS OF OUR CITY.
AND NOW THESE CHILDREN, THIS IS
THE STRAW THAT BREAKS THE
CAMEL'S BACK.
PEOPLE HAVE TO RESPOND.
THEY HAVE TO UNDERSTAND THAT THE
RIGHTS OF THE MANY TO REMAIN
SAFE ARE MORE IMPORTANT THAN ANY
RIGHT YOU MAY THINK YOU HAVE TO
HAVE A MILITARY-STYLE ASSAULT
WEAPON.
>> SENATOR FEINSTEIN, I APPLAUD
WHAT YOU'RE DOING AND I WISH YOU
EVERY SUCCESS.
>> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU, PIERS, I APPRECIATE
IT.
>>> MY NEXT GUEST IS A GUN
RIGHTS ADVOCATE.
HE SAYS THE BUSHMASTER
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE, THE TYPE OF
RIFLE ADAM LANZA USED TO KILL 20
CHILDREN AND SIX MORE ADULTS
SAYS, QUOTE IS A BLAST TO SHOOT
WITH.
HE IS THE PRESIDENT OF THE
VIRGINIA CITIZENS DEFENSE
LEAGUE.
I WANT TO READ WHAT YOU SAID ON
SUNDAY TO THE "WASHINGTON POST."
YOU SAID I COULD ASK YOU WHEN
ASKED ABOUT THE USE OF THESE
TYPE OF WEAPONS WHY SHOULD
ANYONE WANT A FERRARI?
BUSHMASTERS ARE ABSOLUTELY A
BLAST TO SHOOT WITH.
THEY'RE FAST.
THEY'RE ACCURATE.
GUNS ARE FUN.
SOME OF THEM ARE MUCH MORE COOL
THAN OTHERS.
IT'S JUST LIKE WE HAVE
TELEVISION SETS THAT LOOK COOL
AND OTHERS ARE MUCH MORE BOXY.
ARE YOU PROUD OF WHAT YOU SAID?
>> IT'S JUST A FACT.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT FIREARMS.
PEOPLE -- I'M AN INSTRUCTOR.
AND WHEN I TEACH PEOPLE HOW TO
SHOOT, YOU SHOULD SEE THEIR FACE
LIGHT UP THE FIRST TIME THEY
SHOOT A FIREARM.
IT'S LIKE WHAT THEY EXPECTED.
IT IS A LOT OF FUN.
IT'S THE NATURE OF GUNS.
IT'S BEEN A PART OF OUR COUNTRY
FOR 250 YEARS.
>> DO YOU THINK THIS IS A TIME
TO THINK ABOUT GUNS BEING FUN
WHEN 20 CHILDREN AGED 5 YEARS
OLD ARE BEING BLOWN TO PIECES BY
A WEAPON THAT IS FREELY
AVAILABLE IN THIS COUNTRY?
>> WELL, YOU NEED TO ASK THE
REPORTER, BECAUSE HE WAS THE ONE
THAT APPROACHED ME WITH THE
PARTICULAR QUESTIONS.
I SIMPLY ANSWERED THEM.
BECAUSE HE WAS TRYING TO
UNDERSTAND.
HE WAS NOT A GUN PERSON, DIDN'T
UNDERSTAND ANYTHING ABOUT GUNS.
SO I WAS TRYING TO BE HELPFUL.
>> WHY DON'T YOU TRY AND BE
HELPFUL AND EDUCATE ME.
WHY DOES ANYBODY IN AMERICA WHO
IS NOT IN THE MILITARY OR THE
POLICE FORCE NEED A
SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPON THAT CAN
UNLEASH HUNDREDS OF SHOTS IN A
MATTER OF A FEW MINUTES AND
SLAUGHTER INNOCENT AMERICANS?
>> WE DO UNDERSTAND IT'S NOT A
MACHINE GUN.
I JUST WANT TO MAKE THAT CLEAR.
>> I DIDN'T --
>> THIS ISN'T ABOUT MACHINE
GUNS.
>> I UNDERSTAND VERY CAREFULLY.
MY BROTHER IS A BRITISH COLONEL.
I KNOW WHAT WEAPONS ARE.
IT'S A SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE.
IT'S THE SAME RIFLE THAT WAS
USED IN AURORA.
AND I HAVE MANY PEOPLE WHO WERE
AFFECTED BY THAT TONIGHT WITH ME
TONIGHT LIVE AFTER THIS.
AND ALSO IN THE OREGON SHOPPING
MALL SHOOTING.
I KNOW EXACTLY WHAT THIS MACHINE
CAN DO.
I KNOW EXACTLY WHAT IT DID TO
THESE CHILDREN.
I WANT YOU TO TELL ME WHY YOU
CONTINUE TO BELIEVE THAT THIS
WEAPON AND THE TYPE OF WEAPONS
LIKE IT SHOULD BE FREELY
AVAILABLE TO AMERICANS WHEN THEY
ARE BEING USED FOR A SERIES, AND
IT ACCEPT DEEM MICK NOW.
SIX OF THE WORST MASS SHOOTINGS
IN AMERICAN SHOOTINGS HAVE
OCCURRED SINCE 2007.
WHY YOU PERSIST IN WANTING THIS
TO BE FREELY AVAILABLE TO
AMERICANS.
>> WELL, AUTOMOBILES KILL MORE
PEOPLE ON OUR STREETS THAN GUNS
DO, BUT WE DON'T SAY WE
SHOULDN'T HAVE THEM BECAUSE SOME
MANIAC THAT IS DRUNK ENDS UP
DRIVING A CAR INTO A FAMILY AND
KILLING THEM.
THIS WAS A MISUSE OF SOMETHING
BY CLEARLY SOMEBODY THAT WAS
MENTALLY UNSTABLE.
WHY SHOULD THEN THE REST OF THE
COUNTRY WITH THE HUNDREDS OF
MILLIONS OF GUNOWNERS IN AMERICA
THAT DIDN'T DO ANYTHING WRONG
WITH THEIR GUNS, WHY ARE WE
TURNING THEM, AS IF THIS WAS
THEIR FAULT?
THIS IS NOT THEIR FAULT.
THIS WAS A MANIAC IN A STATE
THAT HAD A LOT OF GUN CONTROL IN
A GUN-FREE ZONE THAT IGNORED
EVERY LAW THERE WAS AND MURDERED
ALL THOSE POOR LITTLE CHILDREN.
>> DO YOU WANT ANY MORE FORM OF
GUN CONTROL IN THIS COUNTRY?
YOU'RE QUITE HAPPY WITH WHERE
THINGS ARE?
>> OH, ABSOLUTELY.
CRIME HAS BEEN FALLING IN
AMERICA.
IN FACT, SINCE THE ASSAULT
WEAPON BAN THAT WAS PUT IN PLACE
YEARS AGO BY SENATOR FEINSTEIN,
EVEN WHEN AFTER THAT EXPIRED,
OUR CRIME RATES CONTINUED TO GO
DOWN IN AMERICA.
THE VIOLENT CRIME RATE IS DOWN.
THE ASSAULT WEAPON BAN DIDN'T
DO --
>> HOW MANY PEOPLE GET KILLED
WITH GUNS, GET MURDERED WITH
GUNS A YEAR IN YOUR COUNTRY?
DO YOU KNOW?
>> WELL, MOST OF IT IS EITHER
SUICIDES OR CRIMINAL-ON-CRIMINAL
SHOOTINGS.
>> THAT WASN'T WHAT I ASKED YOU.
WAIT A MINUTE.
>> SOMEWHERE 20,000 --
>> I DIDN'T ASK YOU ABOUT
SUICIDES.
I ASKED YOU HOW MANY PEOPLE WERE
MURDERED WITH GUNS IN AMERICA ON
AVERAGE IN THE LAST TWO OR THREE
YEARS.
DO YOU KNOW THAT FIGURE?
>> I DON'T BECAUSE THE FBI
CLUMPS IT TOGETHER WITH
SUICIDES.
>> THEY DON'T, ACTUALLY.
IT'S VERY EASY TO FIND.
IT'S ABOUT 11,000 TO 12,000.
DO YOU KNOW HOW MANY --
>> I HAVEN'T HEARD THAT NUMBER.
THAT MAKES SENSE.
>> DO YOU KNOW HOW MANY ON
AVERAGE GET KILLED IN BRITAIN OR
GERMANY OR AUSTRALIA?
AND I PARTICULARLY MENTION
BRITAIN AND AUSTRALIA, BECAUSE
IN 1996 WE HAD A VERY SIMILAR
ATTACK IN DUNBLANE IN SCOTLAND
THAT KILLED 16 YOUNG CHILDREN.
WE INSTITUTED A HANDGUN BAN.
IN AUSTRALIA THEY WENT FURTHER.
THEY HAD A GOVERNOR INITIATIVE
TO BRING BACK GUNS.
THEY WOULD GIVE PEOPLE MONEY IN
RETURN FOR THE GUNS.
THEY BANNED ASSAULT WEAPONS OF
THE TYPE YOU'RE SEEING HERE
CAUSING THIS TRAGEDY.
AND GUESS WHAT?
THERE HAVE BEEN NO MORE
SHOOTINGS IN SCHOOLS IN BRITAIN,
IN DUNBLANE SINCE THAT BAN CAME
IN.
AND THERE HAS BEEN NO MASS
SHOOTING IN AUSTRALIA WHATSOEVER
SINCE 1996.
AND I SAY TO YOU --
>> THE CRIME RATES OF GUNS HAVE
DOUBLED.
>> I SAY TO YOU AGAIN, THIS
STATISTIC OF 11,000 TO 12,000
MURDERS FROM GUNS, IT IS WAY,
WAY AHEAD OF ANY OF THE
CIVILIZED COUNTRIES OF THIS
WORLD.
IT IS A DISGRACE TO AMERICA AND
TO THE AMERICAN PEOPLE THAT IT'S
CONTINUED TO HAPPEN.
AND THE REASONS IT HAPPENS, AND
I SAY THIS WITH RESPECT TO YOU,
IS YOUR FACETIOUS ATTITUDE
COMPARING IT TO CARS.
THE FACT THAT EVEN AFTER 20
CHILDREN ARE BLOWN TO PIECES,
YOU STILL SEE NO PROBLEM IN THIS
RIDICULOUS ASSAULT WEAPON BEING
FREELY AVAILABLE ON THE STREETS
OF YOUR COUNTRY, AND THAT MAY BE
A LOAD OF OTHER DERANGED YOUNG
MEN WHO WANT TO MAKE A NAME FOR
THEMSELVES WHO CAN JUST GO AND
GET ONE AND FIND IT EASIER TO
BUY ONE THAT IT IS TO BUY A PET.
THIS IS SHAMEFUL TO AMERICA.
AND PEOPLE LIKE YOU ARE ALLOWING
IT TO CONTINUE.
AND WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT GUNS
BEING FUN ON ABOUT THIS BEING
THE FERRARI OF WEAPONS, I SAY TO
YOU THIS IS NOT THE TIME TO TALK
ABOUT GUNS BEING FUN.
>> WELL, TALK TO THE PRESS ABOUT
THAT.
YOU GUYS, YOU HAVE BEEN PUSHING
THAT ISSUE, ASKING THESE KINDS
OF QUESTIONS.
IF YOU THINK IT'S INAPPROPRIATE
YOU REALLY DO NEED TO TALK TO
SOME OF YOUR FELLOW PEOPLE IN
THE PRESS.
THEY'RE ASKING QUESTIONS LIKE
YOU'RE ASKING QUESTIONS.
I'M TRYING TO ANSWER THEM.
>> THE DAY AFTER 20 CHILDREN ARE
MURDERED TO COMPARE THESE GUNS
TO FERRARIS.
>> HE ASKED ME A SERIES OF
QUESTIONS.
MOST DIDN'T GO ON THERE.
>> YOU ANSWERED THE QUESTIONS.
THEY DIDN'T PUT THE WORDS INTO
YOUR MOUTH.
>> NO.
>> AND I ASKED YOU TODAY IF YOU
WERE PROUD OF THEM, AND YOU
STOOD BY IT.
YOU SAID IT IS THE TRUTH.
>> IT IS THE TRUTH.
YOU WANT ME TO LIE?
POLITICAL CORRECTNESS SHOULDN'T
BE SILENCING --
>> IT'S NOT ABOUT THE TRUTH.
IT'S ABOUT THIS, SIR, WITH
REPRESENT.
IT'S NOT ABOUT THE SECOND
AMENDMENT.
IT'S NOT ABOUT THE BILL OF
RIGHTS THERE ARE ALREADY
EXTENSIVE GUN CONTROLS IN THIS
COUNTRY, EXTENSIVE.
WHAT THIS IS ABOUT IS ABOUT
REACTING TO AN APPALLING
TRAGEDY, THE LIKE OF WHICH
AMERICA HAS NEVER SEEN BEFORE.
IN THE LAST FIVE MONTHS, THERE
HAS BEEN THE WORST EVER SINGLE
SHOOTING IN AURORA, 70 PEOPLE
SHOT.
THERE HAS BEEN THE WORST EVER
SCHOOL SHOOTING, 20 CHILDREN
AGED 5 YEARS OLD.
AND AMERICA --
>> THEY HAPPENED IN GUN-FREE
ZONES.
>> OH, DO STOP BEING SO
FACETIOUS.
>> THEY DO, I'M SERIOUS.
NO, NO, THAT'S NOT BEING
FACETIOUS.
IT HAPPENED WHERE PEOPLE CAN'T
DEFEND THEMSELVES.
>> SO YOU BELIEVE THIS THEORY,
THAT IF EVERYONE IN THAT MOVIE
THEATER WAS ARMED, THEY WOULD
HAVE ALL STOOD UP --
>> NOT EVERYONE.
>> HOW MANY DO YOU WANT TO BE
ARMED IN THAT MOVIE THEATER?
>> I BELIEVE SOMEBODY FIRING AT
HIM WOULD HAVE SLOWED HIM DOWN
OR POSSIBLY STOPPED HIM, YES.
>> YOU'RE AWARE OF THE
SHOOTING --
>> NOT BEEN ABLE TO CARRY THEM
OUT.
>> YOU'RE AWARE OF THE SHOOTING
IN NEW YORK RECENTLY WHERE
POLICE FIRED, AND THESE ARE
EXPERT MARKSMEN, USED TO
HANDLING FIREARMS ACTUALLY SHOT
EIGHT PEOPLE.
YOU WERE AWARE OF THAT.
THEY WERE POLICE OFFICERS.
>> I WAS A DEPUTY SHERIFF.
SO I KNOW A LITTLE BIT MORE
ABOUT LAW ENFORCEMENT THAN YOU
DO.
>> REALLY?
>> AND THE HIGHLY -- YES.
>> YOU EXPLAIN TO ME, THEN.
>> PATROL OFFICER IS NOT WHAT
YOU THINK IT IS.
>> YOU EXPLAIN TO ME WHY YOU
THINK ARMING EVERY MOVIE
THEATER, SHOPPING MALL, AND
SCHOOL IN THIS COUNTRY WHEN YOU
ALREADY HAVE 300 MILLION GUNS IS
GOING TO HELP THIS APPALLING
CULTURE OF GUN VIOLENCE IN
AMERICA.
YOU TELL ME.
>> OKAY.
>> EVEN AS I SPEAK.
>> I CAN TELL YOU GUN SALES WILL
BE RISING IN CONNECTICUT BECAUSE
OF PEOPLE LIKE YOU.
PEOPLE WILL BE SAYING I'VE GOT
TO ARM MYSELF.
AND EVERY TIME IT HAPPENS, MORE
GUNS GET INTO CIRCULATION, AND
MORE OF THESE OUTRAGES HAPPEN.
AND AT SOME POINT, YOU AND YOUR
COLLEAGUES WHO SUPPORT NO EXTRA
GUN CONTROL ARE GOING TO HAVE TO
WAKE UP AND SMELL THE COFFEE.
>> ACTUALLY FEINSTEIN'S BILL
WHEN SHE PUTS THAT IN, YOU'RE
GOING TO SEE A RISE IN ASSAULT
WEAPONS LIKE YOU'VE NEVER
IMAGINED.
SO IT'S GOING TO WORK JUST THE
OPPOSITE OF WHAT SHE WANTS.
GUN CONTROL NEVER WORK.
IT FAILS EVERYWHERE IT IS TRIED.
AND THIS WILL JUST BE ANOTHER
EXAMPLE IF SHE EVER DOES GET IT
PASSED.
>> I ALREADY SAID TO YOU GUN
CONTROL HAS WORKED VERY
SUCCESSFULLY IN BRITAIN, IN
AUSTRALIA, IN JAPAN.
JAPAN HAS THE TOUGHEST GUN
CONTROL IN THE WORLD.
THEY HAVE TWO OR THREE MURDERS A
YEAR.
YOU HAVE 11,000 TO 12,000 --
>> HOW MANY SUICIDES DO THEY
HAVE?
>> 11,000 TO 12,000 MURDERS FROM
GUNS A YEAR IN AMERICA.
AND YOU STILL DON'T CARE, DO
YOU?
>> SUICIDES ARE HIGHER IN JAPAN
THAN THEY ARE IN AMERICA.
THEY DON'T USE GUNS.
THEY HAVE ALL KINDS OF WAYS TO
KILL THEMSELVES.
AND YOU HAVE A DIFFERENT CULTURE
IN ENGLAND.
WHAT HAS HURT THIS COUNTRY IS
THE DRUGS.
THE DRUGS HAVE CHANGED
EVERYTHING.
YOU DIDN'T HEAR ABOUT THESE
SHOOTINGS WHEN I WAS GROWING UP
IN THE '50s AND '60s.
AND THEN YOU DIDN'T NEED A
BACKGROUND CHECK TO BUY A GUN.
NOW WITH ALL THE DRUGS, ALL THE
STUFF WE'RE TREATING KIDS WITH
THESE PSYCHOTIC DRUGS, IT'S
CAUSING SOME REAL PROBLEMS IN
OUR COMMUNITY.
ALMOST ALL OF THESE KIDS THAT
HAVE MURDERED, IF YOU LOOK AT
THEM, THEY HAVE BEEN TREATED
WITH DRUGS FOR THEIR MENTAL
PROBLEMS.
AND IT'S CHANGING SOMETHING.
IT'S TAKING AWAY THEIR EMPATHY
WHERE THEY CAN DO THIS KIND OF
HORRIBLE THING AND NOT FEEL
REMORSE OR FEAR OR TERROR OF
WHAT THEY'RE DOING.
THEY JUST GO ON LIKE A MACHINE.
THAT'S THE PROBLEM IN AMERICA.
IT'S DRUGS MORE THAN ANYTHING.
>> I'M GLAD YOU'VE TOLD ME WHAT
THE PROBLEM IS, PHILIP.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING ME.
WHEN WE COME BACK, I'LL TALK TO
THE PEOPLE SITTING WITH ME HERE
IN THE STUDIO.
THEY'RE ALL FAMILY MEMBERS AND
SURVIVORS OF THE AURORA MASSACRE
IN COLORADO.
YOU'RE GOING TO WHATEVER THAT
THEY HAVE TO SAY WHAT THEY JUST
HEARD FROM SOMEBODY WHO DOESN'T
BELIEVE THERE IS ANY NEED FOR
GUN CONTROL IN AMERICA.
THINGS ARE FINE JUST THE WAY
THEY ARE.
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA THINS
PACK THE BIG TASTE
OF GRANOLA AND DARK CHOCOLATE
INTO ONE PERFECT SQUARE,
UNDER 100 CALORIES.
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA THINS.
UP HIGH!
OK. DON'T YOU HAVE
ANY USEFULL APPS ON THAT THING?
WHO DO YOU THINK I AM,
Quicken Loans?
♪
AT Quicken Loans,
OUR AMAZINGLY USEFUL
MORTGAGE CALCULATOR APP
ALLOWS YOU TO QUICKLY CALCULATE
YOUR MORTGAGE PAYMENT
BASED ON TODAY'S INCREDIBLY LOW
INTEREST RATES...
RIGHT FROM YOUR IPHONE
OR ANDROID SMARTPHONE.
ONE MORE WAY Quicken Loans
IS ENGINEERED TO AMAZE.
♪
>>> WELCOME BACK.
THE PEOPLE SITTING WITH ME NOW
EACH THIS THEIR OWN WAYS HAVE
EXPERIENCED GUN TRAGEDY.
THE MASSACRE IN AURORA,
COLORADO.
WE ALSO HAVE A SURVIVOR OF THAT
ATTACK, AND THE MAN WHOSE
BROTHER WAS INJURED IN THE
SHOOTING AT THE EMPIRE STATE
BUILDING.
THEY'RE ALL HERE TO SPEAK OUT IN
SOLIDARITY WITH THE PEOPLE OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
FIRST IN LEE SHULL.
YOU'RE LEADING A CAMPAIGN REALLY
FROM NEWTOWN.
TELL ME ABOUT THIS.
>> PIERS, THANK YOU FOR HAVING
ME ON.
FIRST I WANT TO EXPRESS MY
CONDOLENCES TO EVERYBODY IN OUR
COMMUNITY SUFFERING THROUGH
THIS, NOT ONLY THE 27 VICTIMS,
BUT THE CHILDREN AND THE
TEACHERS THAT EXPERIENCED THE
TRAGEDY THEMSELVES.
THEY ARE SUFFERING FROM THIS AND
HAVE TO RELIVE THESE EVENTS.
SO OUR HEARTS GO OUT TO THEM.
>> WHAT IS IT THAT YOU WOULD
MOST LIKE TO SEE HAPPEN?
WE HEARD THE PRESIDENT YESTERDAY
TALK VERY PASSIONATELY ABOUT THE
NEED TO DO SOMETHING, THAT DOING
NOTHING WAS NO LONGER AN OPTION.
WHAT SHOULD THAT SOMETHING BE?
>> I THINK IT'S A MULTITUDE OF
THINGS, PIERS.
IT'S REASONABLE GUN CONTROL.
IT'S LOOKING AT EMOTIONAL
INSTABILITY.
IT'S EMPATHY AND COMPASSION FOR
OUR FELLOW HUMAN BEING.
IT REALLY IS A MULTITUDE OF
THINGS.
>> IN RELATION TO THE DEBATE
ABOUT GUN CONTROL, IT SEEMS TO
BE INCREASINGLY FOCUSED NOW ON
THESE SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLES AND
THE HIGH CAPACITY MAGAZINES.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO SEE A BAN ON
BOTH OF THOSE THINGS, AS SENATOR
FEINSTEIN IS TRYING TO PUSH
THROUGH?
>> YES, I ABSOLUTELY WOULD.
>> YOU THINK THE AMERICAN --
>> I THINK MOST OF OUR
COMMUNITY -- EXCUSE ME.
>> NO, PLEASE.
AFTER YOU.
>> I THINK MOST OF OUR COMMUNITY
IS ON BOARD.
I JUST CAME FROM A MEETING, AND
THE MAJORITY OF PEOPLE WANT AN
IMMEDIATE ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN,
STARTING IN OUR COMMUNITY.
>> HOW IS YOUR DAUGHTER?
SHE HAS LOST THREE OF HER
FRIENDS.
IT MUST HAVE BEEN UNBELIEVABLY
TRAUMATIC FOR HER.
>> WELL, SHE WASN'T CLOSE WITH
THEM BECAUSE THEY WERE SO
DIFFERENT IN AGE.
BUT THEY ARE FROM HER DANCE
STUDIO.
BUT WE HAVE THREE DEATHS WITHIN
OUR NEIGHBORHOOD.
THE SHOOTER LIVED WITHIN MY
NEIGHBORHOOD.
WE LOST OUR FORMER BABY-SITTER,
LOST HER MOTHER.
SO IT'S ON MULTIPLE FRONTS.
>> HOW DO YOU THINK THE
COMMUNITY IS DOING THERE?
>> THEY'RE VERY STRONG.
THEY'RE COMING TOGETHER.
IT'S REALLY -- THESE LAST TWO
DAYS HAVE BEEN A HORROR.
PEOPLE ARE UP IN ARMS.
PEOPLE ARE MOTIVED TO DO
SOMETHING AND TO BE CALLED TO
ACTION.
PEOPLE WANT TO HELP.
>> AND AS PEOPLE ARE WATCHING
THIS AND WANT TO KNOW HOW THEY
CAN HELP, WHAT IS THE BEST WAY
FOR PEOPLE OUTSIDE OF NEWTOWN TO
CONTRIBUTE?
>> WELL, TO CONTRIBUTE I THINK
FOR OUR COUNTRY, BECAUSE IT'S
REALLY ABOUT OUR COUNTRY, IF
IT'S ONLY NEWTOWN THAT GOES
THROUGH THESE CHANGES AND TRIES
TO EFFECT THESE THINGS, THAT'S
ONE SMALL PART.
WE ALL HAVE TO -- EVERY
COMMUNITY IN THIS NATION NEEDS
TO UNDERSTAND THAT THIS CAN
HAPPEN IF WE HAVE PROLIFERATION
OF GUNS AND EMOTIONAL
INSTABILITY IN YOUR COMMUNITY,
THIS CAN HAPPEN.
AND WE NEED ALL COMMUNITIES,
BASICALLY, TO RALLY THEIR LOCAL
AND STATE GOVERNMENT, FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT, AND GET OUR ELECTED
OFFICIALS TO HAVE THE MORAL
COURAGE TO SIT DOWN WITH EACH
OTHER AND HAVE COMMON SENSE
DISCUSSIONS AND LISTEN TO EACH
OTHER AND LISTEN TO THEIR POINTS
AND FIND SOME MIDDLE COMMON
GROUND.
>> LEE SHULL, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH FOR JOINING ME.
I DO APPRECIATE IT.
>> THANK YOU.
>> NOW I WANT TO BRING IN MY
SPECIAL GUESTS HERE IN THE
STUDIO, LOVED ONES OF THE
VICTIMS OF THE AURORA, COLORADO,
SHOOTING, AND A SURVIVOR.
WELCOME TO YOU ALL.
EVEN WHEN I'VE TALKED TO YOU IN
OUR GREEN ROOM, A LOT OF
EMOTION, A LOT OF ANGER, A LOT
OF GREAT SADNESS.
I CAN ONLY BEGIN TO IMAGINE HOW
YOU'VE ALL BEEN HEARING THAT SO
SOON AFTER WHAT HAPPENED IN
AURORA, ARGUABLY AN EVEN WORSE
TRAGEDY.
20 5-YEAR-OLD CHILDREN BLOWN TO
PIECES.
STEPHEN, LET ME START WITH THAT.
YOU WERE A VICTIM IN AURORA.
YOU WERE SHOT.
HOW YOU DOING PHYSICALLY, FIRST
OF ALL?
>> I'M SLOWLY RECOVERING.
SOME NERVE DAMAGE IN MY LEFT
ARM.
BUT ALL THINGS CONSIDERED, DOING
REALLY WELL.
>> IT'S NEARLY FIVE MONTHS TO
THE DAY SINCE THE MASSACRE IN
THAT MOVIE THEATER.
AND WE SEE THIS INCIDENT
HAPPENING IN NEWTOWN.
IT'S JUST BEYOND GROTESQUE.
WHAT WERE YOUR FEELINGS WHEN YOU
HEARD OF HAD HAPPENED COMING TO
SOON AFTER WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU?
>> YEAH, I SAW THE INITIAL
REPORTS LIKE EVERYONE DID, THAT
MAYBE JUST THE SHOOTER HAD BEEN
KILLED.
AND ALL OF THE SUDDEN IT WAS 27
PEOPLE MURDERED.
AND GROWING UP, HAVING GROWN UP
TEN MINUTES DOWN THE ROAD FROM
THAT COMMUNITY, I COULDN'T
BELIEVE THAT ONCE AGAIN MY LIFE
WAS GOING TO BE AFFECTED IN THIS
WAY BY SUCH HORRIBLE VIOLENCE.
>> YOU ACTUALLY LIVE LITERALLY
TEN MINUTES AWAY?
>> RIGHT.
THAT'S WHERE I GREW UP MY WHOLE
LIFE.
>> WHAT DOES THIS SAY ABOUT
AMERICA THAT YOU'RE ATTACKED IN
A MOVIE THEATER BY A YOUNG MAN
WITH AN AR-15 ASSAULT RIFLE AND
THEN TEN MINUTES AWAY FROM WHERE
YOU LIVE, AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IS SHOT UP WITH A YOUNG MAN WITH
EXACTLY THE SAME WEAPON?
>> IT'S CERTAINLY DISCOURAGING
IN SOME SENSE.
BUT, YOU KNOW, WHAT CAME AFTER
AURORA AND WHAT IS COMING AFTER
THIS HORRIBLE EVENT IS COMMUNITY
COMING TOGETHER, BANDING
TOGETHER IN AN INCREDIBLY
POSITIVE WAY.
AND I MEAN, THE SUPPORT I
RECEIVED FROM STRANGERS AFTER
AURORA IS AMAZING.
AND IT'S CLEAR IN SANDY HOOK THE
SAME THING IS HAPPENING THERE.
>> THERESA AND DAVE, LET ME
RETURN TO YOU.
A.J. BOIK WAS YOUR SON.
HE WAS YOUR NEPHEW, DAVE.
THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES SAID LAST NIGHT THAT
THERE ARE FOUR OUTRAGES NOW ON
HIS WATCH INVOLVING MASS
SHOOTINGS.
HE'S GOT TO DO SOMETHING.
I KNOW YOU MET WITH THE
PRESIDENT AFTER WHAT HAPPENED IN
AURORA.
WHAT DID HE SAY TO YOU THEN,
DAVE, AND WHAT HAPPENED?
>> WE WERE ALL GATHERED IN
AURORA, AND WE WERE SITTING IN
THE ROOM, WAITING FOR THE
PRESIDENT TO ARRIVE.
AND HE WALKED IN AND GRACIOUS.
IT WAS A VERY POSITIVE MEETING.
BUT HE STARTED IT OUT WITH I'M
NOT HERE AS THE PRESIDENT.
I'M HERE AS A FATHER.
I'M HERE AS A PARENT.
MY CHILDREN GO TO THE MOVIES.
WE NEED TO MAKE A CHANGE.
WE NEED TO BE HOLDING OUR
ELECTED OFFICIALS ACCOUNTABLE.
WE NEED TO MAKE POSITIVE CHANGE
BECAUSE IT'S TOO LATE FOR A.J.,
BUT THERE ARE OTHER CHILDREN
THROUGHOUT THAT ARE GOING TO BE
AFFECTED IF WE DON'T DO
SOMETHING ABOUT IT.
AND TO THROW OUR HANDS UP AND TO
WALK AWAY FROM THIS ISSUE IS
LIKE SAYING IT'S OKAY THAT THIS
HAPPENED.
WE AREN'T GOING TO DO ANYTHING
ELSE ABOUT IT.
WE CAN'T CHANGE IT.
WELL, THAT'S GARBAGE.
AND WHAT WE NEED TO DO NOW IS
REMEMBER THAT WE HAVE TO TAKE
OUR COMMUNITY BACK.
WE HAVE TO TAKE OUR WORLD BACK.
AND WE HAVE TO SAY THIS IS
UNACCEPTABLE.
WE HAVE LAWS ON THE BOOKS THAT
SAY IT'S ILLEGAL TO STEAL.
BUT GUESS WHAT?
THOSE LAWS ARE STILL THERE
BECAUSE IT'S UNACCEPTABLE
BEHAVIOR.
AND THAT'S WHAT WE HAVE TO DO
WITH GUNS.
WE HAVE TO SAY THIS IS
UNACCEPTABLE.
WE DON'T NEED THIS INDIVIDUAL TO
HAVE A GUN.
WE DON'T NEED -- WE NEED TO HAVE
BACKGROUND CHECKS DONE ON
EVERYBODY THAT PURCHASES A
FIREARM SO THAT WE CAN STOP
THESE INDIVIDUALS FROM GETTING
THE GUNS AND MAKE IT DIFFICULT
FOR THEM TO GET THESE WEAPONS,
BECAUSE IT'S JUST A MATTER OF
TIME BEFORE THIS WREAKS HAVOC
AGAIN.
>> THERESA, THIS WAS YOUR BOY.
HE WAS 18.
>> YES.
>> WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THE
PARENTS IN SANDY HOOK NOW WHO
ARE TRYING TO SOMEHOW DEAL WITH
THIS?
>> WE ARE BEHIND THEM 100%.
UNFORTUNATELY, WE KNOW EXACTLY
WHAT THEY'RE GOING THROUGH.
IT'S A TERRIBLE CLUB.
BUT IT'S -- IT'S THE HARDEST
THING YOU'RE EVER GOING TO GO
THROUGH.
AND YOU HAVE TO -- YOU HAVE TO
HAVE FAITH AND PUSH YOUR -- PUSH
YOUR -- PUSH THIS LEGISLATION
THROUGH.
YOU GOT TO CALL YOUR CONGRESS.
YOU GOT TO LET EVERYONE KNOW.
SCREAM IT FROM THE HILLS.
IT'S UNACCEPTABLE.
COLUMBINE SHOULDN'T HAVE
HAPPENED.
AURORA SHOULDN'T HAVE HAPPENED.
VIRGINIA TECH SHOULDN'T HAVE
HAPPENED.
AND GOD FORBID THIS SHOULDN'T
HAVE HAPPENED EITHER AT SANDY
HOOK.
IT SHOULD NOT.
>> AND CAREN, YOUR SON ALEX, HE
WAS 24.
HE FLUNG HIMSELF ON HIS
GIRLFRIEND AND SAVED HER, BUT HE
LOST HIS LIFE.
A HERO.
WHEN YOU SEE WHAT HAS HAPPENED
SO SOON AFTERWARDS, ANOTHER
OUTRAGE, MORE FAMILIES
DECIMATED.
AND YOU SEE THE GUN RIGHTS GUY
TONIGHT, HE DOESN'T WANT TO DO
ANYTHING.
HE THINKS GUNS ARE FUN.
YOU CAN'T PROHIBIT PEOPLE'S
RIGHTS UNDER THE SECOND
AMENDMENT.
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THAT?
>> I SAY TO THEM IT'S NOT ABOUT
THEIR SECOND AMENDMENT RIGHTS.
IT'S NOT ABOUT OUR SECOND
AMENDMENT RIGHTS.
IT'S ABOUT OUR RIGHTS, OUR
CHILDREN'S RIGHTS TO JUST BE
ABLE TO GO TO A MOVIE, TO JUST
GO TO CHURCH, TO GO TO SCHOOL.
THEY HAVE A RIGHT TO DO THAT IN
A SAFE ENVIRONMENT.
AND I THINK WE AS AMERICANS JUST
NEED TO RISE TOGETHER AND SAY
WE'VE HAD ENOUGH OF THIS.
WE'RE BETTER THAN THIS.
WE -- WE NEED TO REALLY RAISE
OUR VOICES AND BAND TOGETHER AND
LET OUR LEADERS HEAR US.
WE CAN'T JUST TURN OFF THE TV
AND WALK AWAY.
WE HAVE TO BE STRONG TOGETHER
LIKE WE ARE TOGETHER.
AND THE SANDY HOOK FAMILIES, I'M
SURE THEY'RE TOGETHER, HOLDING
EACH OTHER.
BECAUSE IT'S THE MOST HORRIBLE
NIGHTMARE YOU CAN EVER IMAGINE.
AND WE JUST HAVE TO HAVE OUR
VOICES HEARD.
>> LET'S TAKE A BREAK.
WE'LL COME BACK.
MUCH MORE.
MORE POWERFUL STORIES FROM
PEOPLE.
THESE INTEREST PEOPLE WHO REALLY
SHOULD BE DOING THE TALKING.
THEY'VE HAD TO LIVE THROUGH
THIS.
THEY'VE LOST THEIR LOVED ONES TO
GUNS, TO MASSACRES.
AND THEY WANT ACTION.
I'LL TALK TO THEM MORE AFTER THE
BREAK.
w?
>>> WITH ME NOW ARE FAMILY
MEMBERS, VICTIMS OF A TRAGIC
MASS SHOOTING IN AURORA,
COLORADO, FIVE MONTHS AGO.
SANDY AND LONNIE, YOU LOST
JESSICA, YOUR DAUGHTER.
SHE WAS 24 YEARS OLD.
SHE WAS AT THAT MOVIE THEATER,
HAD GONE TO SEE A MOVIE, AND SHE
NEVER CAME HOME.
YOU WERE TELLING ME A TOUCHING
STORY ABOUT YOUR SON.
TELL ME ABOUT THAT.
>> AFTER HE WENT TO AURORA AND
TOOK CARE OF THE ARRANGEMENTS TO
HAVE JESSIE CREMATED AND BRING
HER HOME, ONCE HE GOT HOME, HE
VERY QUIETLY WITHOUT TELLING US
SOLD HIS RIFLE.
>> IT WAS AN AR-15?
>> IT WAS AN AR-15.
WHEN HE GOT HOME, HE JUST
STARTED THINKING ABOUT IT AND
WENT THIS IS THE RIGHT THING TO
DO, AND SOLD IT.
>> LONNIE, WHEN YOU CAME ON MY
SHOW LAST WEEK, AFTER ANOTHER
SHOOTING IN THE SHOPPING MALL IN
OREGON, YOU BOTH ARE SUPPORTERS
OF GUNS.
AND YOU THOUGHT ABOUT BEING
ANTI-GUN, WHICH IS ONE OF THE
MYTHS OF THIS DEBATE.
IT'S JUST YOU WANT TO GET RID OF
ALL GUNS.
THAT'S NOT THE CORRECT DEBATE,
IT IS?
>> NO, ACTUALLY, IT'S NOT.
IN THIS CASE, THE SHOOTINGS HAD
JUST HAPPENED.
THIS WOMAN WHOSE SON MURDERED
HER AND MURDERED THE CHILDREN,
IF SHE HAD BOUGHT MAYBE A GUN
SAFE INSTEAD OF THE AR-15, SHE
WOULD STILL BE ALIVE, AND SO
WOULD ALL THOSE CHILDREN.
WE DO NEED TO CHANGE THE LAWS.
IF WE COULD START WITH BABY
STEPS EVEN.
WE DON'T HAVE TO DEMAND THAT THE
AR-15 WOULD BE BANNED, BUT IT IS
A GREAT IDEA, AND I'M SURE A LOT
OF PEOPLE WOULD AGREE WITH THAT.
BUT YOU USE COMMON SENSE.
GUNOWNERS -- I'M A GUNOWNER.
I'M GOING TO CONTINUE TO BE A
GUNOWNER.
I'M GOING TO PROTECT MY HOUSE.
I DON'T THINK ANYBODY IN -- THE
BURGLARS IN TEXAS THAT.
>> WAIT UNTIL YOU'RE GONE BEFORE
THEY BREAK INTO YOUR HOUSE,
BECAUSE IT'S A FINAL JUDGMENT
WHEN YOU GET BLOWN AWAY WITH A
SHOTGUN.
BUT THE GUN LAWS IN OUR COUNTRY
NEED TO BE ENFORCED WHAT WE
HAVE.
WE NEED TO IMPROVE THEM.
WE NEED, LIKE DAVE SAID, WE NEED
TO HAVE A SENSIBLE REGISTRATION.
WE ALSO NEED TO LOOK AT THE
PEOPLE THAT GET AHOLD OF THESE
GUNS.
THE LAST FOUR KILLINGS HAVE BEEN
BY UNSTABLE MENTAL PEOPLE.
>> LET ME BRING YOU IN HERE.
YOU RUN THE BRADY CAMPAIGN.
BUT YOU HAVE A CONNECTION.
YOUR OWN BROTHER WAS SHOT AT A
SHOOTING OF THE EMPIRE STATE
BUILDING IN THE LATE '90s.
WE'VE DEBATED THIS A LOT THIS
WEEK WITH LOTS OF PEOPLE.
IT'S A VERY EMOTIVE DEBATE.
DO YOU FEEL THAT WE HAVE GOT TO
A TIPPING POINT HERE, THAT THE
MOOD HAS CHANGED?
BECAUSE I FEEL IT HAS.
>> UNDOUBTEDLY.
AND THE BIG REASON IS BECAUSE
THESE VOICES THAT YOU HEAR, HAVE
HERE ON YOUR SHOW TONIGHT ARE
BEING HEARD.
THESE INTEREST VOICES THAT NEED
TO BE HEARD.
ONE IN THREE AMERICANS KNOW
SOMEBODY WHO HAS BEEN SHOT.
WE'RE NOT AS UNIQUE AS IT MIGHT
SEEM.
32 PEOPLE IN OUR COUNTRY ARE
MURDERED WITH GUNS EVERY SINGLE
DAY, AND THE REALITY IS THE ONLY
PLACE WHERE THIS IS A PARTISAN
POLITICAL DEBATE IS IN THE HALLS
OF CONGRESS.
AND WHAT THIS TRAGEDY IS DOING
IS IT'S EXPOSING THAT DISCONNECT
BETWEEN WHAT THE AMERICAN PEOPLE
WANT AND THE CONVERSATION WE
WANT TO HAVE AND WHAT OUR
ELECTED OFFICIALS ARE DOING
ABOUT IT.
AND TOMORROW WE'RE ALL GOING TO
WASHINGTON, D.C. TO DELIVER 245
MESSAGE TO CONGRESS AND THE
PRESIDENT.
>> IT SHOULDN'T BE A POLITICAL
ISSUE.
>> NO.
>> IN AUSTRALIA AND IN BRITAIN
WHEN THEY HAD THE SIMILAR
OUTRAGES, IT WASN'T ABOUT
POLITICS.
IT WASN'T LEFT OR RIGHT.
>> NO.
>> IT WAS ABOUT PEOPLE POWER
GETTING ACTION.
JESSICA, LET ME COME TO YOU.
BECAUSE YOU HAVE A QUITE
EXTRAORDINARY STORY.
AND TELL ME QUICKLY THE
CONNECTIONS YOU HAVE TO VARIOUS
MASS SHOOTINGS.
>> MY HUSBAND WAS A STUDENT AT
COLUMBINE.
HE WAS UNINJURED, BUT
EMOTIONALLY SCARRED.
>> HE SAW TWO STUDENTS KILLED?
>> CORRECT.
AND THEN THE LITTLE GIRL I BABY
SAT WAS KILLED IN PLATTE CANYON
HIGH SCHOOL IN BAILEY, COLORADO
IN 2006.
>> SHE WAS SHOT DEAD?
>> SHE WAS SHOT DEAD.
AND BY A DERANGED GUNMAN WHO
RANDOMLY ENTERED THAT SCHOOL.
AND THEN MY COUSIN WAS KILLED AT
THE AURORA THEATER.
AND SITTING NEXT TO HIM WAS MY
MIDDLE SCHOOL AND HIGH SCHOOL
CLASSMATE, AND HE WAS SHOT THREE
TIMES, BUT SURVIVED.
>> AND JUST PURE CHANCE.
THEY DID NOT KNOW EACH OTHER.
>> THEY DID NOT KNOW EACH OTHER.
>> SO YOU HAVE AN ASTONISHING
CONNECTION TO SO MANY OF THESE
MASS SHOOTINGS.
>> YES.
>> SO THROUGHOUT YOUR LIFE,
YOU'VE BEEN TAINTED BY WHAT IS
GOING ON.
>> UH-HUH.
>> WHY ARE THE AMERICANS SO
RELUCTANT TO COLLECTIVELY RISE
UP AND DEMAND ACTION, DO YOU
THINK?
>> BECAUSE I THINK IT REALLY
TAKES SOMEBODY IN OUR POSITION
ONCE WE'VE LOST SOMEBODY, ONCE
WE'VE KNOWN SOMEBODY WHO IS
INJURED AND ARE -- THEY'VE GOT
LASTING POST TRAUMATIC STRESS
SYNDROME TO REALLY SEE THE
EFFECTS AND DAMAGES IT CAUSES,
BECAUSE IT'S UNFORTUNATELY A
VERY UNIQUE CLUB.
>> JERRI, LET ME BRING YOU IN
HERE.
YOUR SON MATT, HE WAS 27.
HE ALSO DIED SHIELDING HIS
GIRLFRIEND, ANOTHER HERO IN
AURORA IN THAT MOVIE THEATER.
YOU WERE TELLING ME THAT HIS
GRANDFATHER WAS IN THE POLICE.
AND HE WAS BROUGHT UP IN A
FAMILY THAT RESPECTED GUNS.
>> YES.
HE PROBABLY STARTED LEARNING THE
RESPECT OF GUNS, LIKE YOU SAID,
MY FATHER WAS A POLICE OFFICER
FOR 23 YEARS.
AND WHEN MY BOYS WERE LITTLE, HE
WOULD TAKE THEM TO HIS SHOOTING
RANGE ON HIS PROPERTY.
BUT HE ALSO TAUGHT THEM NOT ONLY
HOW TO SHOOT A GUN, BUT HOW TO
RESPECT IT.
AND SO WE'RE NOT -- AS FAR AS
OUR FAMILY IS CONCERNED, MY
HUSBAND AND I WERE NOT AGAINST
GUNS.
IT'S JUST THAT NOBODY NEEDS
THESE AR-15s.
IF YOU'RE GOING TO HUNT, YOU'RE
NOT GOING TO SHOOT.
>> THESE ARE MILITARY WEAPONS.
>> RIGHT.
>> TO FIRE OFF 100
MAGAZINE-POWERED GUNS IN THE WAY
THAT HAPPENED IN AURORA, NO
AMERICAN CIVILIAN NEEDS THAT
OUTSIDE OF THE MILITARY AND THE
POLICE FORCE.
THAT IS WHAT ANGERS ME.
THAT'S WHAT THE DEBATE SHOULD BE
FOCUSED ON.
AMANDA WAS YOUR SISTER, MICAYLA,
WHO DIED AT 23 IN AURORA.
AND ANITA, YOUR COUSIN.
NOT ONLY DO YOU FEEL STRONGLY
ABOUT THE FUNDRAISING THAT WENT
ON AFTER THIS.
MILLIONS OF DOLLARS POURS IN.
YOU'RE CONCERNED WHAT HAPPENS
WITH IT AND PEOPLE TRYING TO
HELP WITH WHAT HAPPENED TO THE
FAMILIES AT SANDY HOOK.
>> WE LEARNED A LOT IN AURORA
WITH PEOPLE.
AFTER ONE OF THESE NATIONAL
TRAGEDIES HAPPENS, THERE IS ALL
THESE FUNDS STARTING UP THAT
PEOPLE WANT TO HELP.
AND THE AMERICAN PEOPLE ARE VERY
GENEROUS AND VERY GRACIOUS.
AND THEY DO WANT TO HELP.
AND THEY GIVE MONEY, AND THEY
GIVE MONEY TO NONPROFITS.
AND WHAT WE FOUND IN AURORA IS
THAT THEY WERE GIVING MONEY TO A
NONPROFIT THAT THEN GIVES TO IT
OTHER NONPROFITS.
WE'VE STARTED AS A GROUP
EVERYONE HERE A ORGANIZATION
CALLED VICTIMS FIRST.
VICTIMSFIRST.ORG.
AND WE ARE GOING TO MAKE SURE
THAT THE SANDY HOOK VICTIMS DO
NOT GET VICTIMIZED LIKE WE DID
THIS.
HAPPENED TO THE VICTIMS OF 9/11
WHERE A HANDFUL OF FAMILIES HAD
TO STAND UP AND STOP THE MONEY
FROM GOING ELSEWHERE.
IT HAPPENED JUST RECENTLY WITH
HURRICANE SANDY.
YOU HAD THE STATEN ISLAND
BOROUGH PRESIDENT COME OUT AND
SAY STOP GIVING MONEY.
WE'RE NOT SEEING ANY OF IT.
AND IT'S JUST GOT TO STOP.
>> IT'S A GREAT POINT.
AND I WISH YOU EVERY SUCCESS
WITH THAT, AMANDA.
I CAN SEE YOU'RE VERY DISTRAUGHT
ABOUT THIS.
IF THERE IS ONE THING YOU COULD
SAY TO PEOPLE ABOUT GUNS, WHAT
WOULD YOU SAY?
>> GOD, PIERS, PUT ME ON THE
SPOT HERE.
I'M ABSOLUTELY AGAINST GUNS IN
ANY FASHION.
HUNT ME SOME DEER, BUT GOD, WE
DON'T NEED THEM ON THE STREETS
IN ANY FASHION.
>> I THINK THE WORDS EVERYONE
SHOULD TAKE EXTREMELY SERIOUSLY,
ESPECIALLY COMING FROM FAMILIES
SUCH AS YOURS.
THANK YOU ALL VERY MUCH FOR
JOINING ME.
STAY WHERE YOU ARE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SAYS HE WILL USE
THE POWER OF HIS OFFICE TO
ENSURE THERE ARE NO MORE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THE ONE IN
CONNECTICUT.
THIS IS A MOMENT WHEN THE GUN
POLICIES WILL CHANGE.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT THAT WHEN WE
COME BACK.
lower cholesterol
as part
of a heart healthy diet.
That's true.
...But you still have to go
to the gym.
♪ The one and only, Cheerios
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID LAST
NIGHT IN NEWTOWN HE WAS GOING TO
DO SOMETHING.
THE QUESTION IS WHAT WILL HE DO?
JOINING ME IS CHARLES BLOW FROM
"THE NEW YORK TIMES."
THE PRESIDENT SEEMED PRETTY
FIRED UP AND HE SEEMED PRETTY
DETERMINED.
IS HE GOING TO DO ANYTHING?
AND IF HE DOES, WHAT IS HE GOING
TO DO?
>> THAT'S THE QUESTION.
WE'VE HAD AT LEAST FOR THE LAST
FIVE YEARS IF NOT FOR THE LAST
TEN IS A DAMPENING DOWN OF KIND
OF DISCUSSION OF PEOPLE WHO WANT
TO SEE SOME SORT OF SENSIBLE GUN
CONTROL RESTRICTIONS.
AND IN THAT VOID, THE NRA AND
GUN, PRO-GUN ADVOCATES HAVE
ACTUALLY GROWN STRONGER.
YOU WOW WOULD HAVE THOUGHT MAYBE
THEY SAW THERE WASN'T AS MUCH
OPPOSITION AND DIDN'T HAVE TO
SPEND MUCH MONEY.
IN FACT, THEIR SPENDING HAS
INCREASED.
SO NOW YOU HAVE THE BIGGEST GUN
CONTROL LOBBY IS PROBABLY ONE
PEOPLE KNOW MOST IS THE BRADY
CAMPAIGN.
THE NRA SPENDS ABOUT 66 TIMES AS
MUCH ON LOBBYING AS THE BRADY
CAMPAIGN.
AND THEY SPENT DURING THE
CAMPAIGN CONTRIBUTING TO
CANDIDATES 4100 TIMES AS MUCH AS
THE BRADY CAMPAIGN.
THIS HAS NOW BECOME A ONE-SIDED
DISCUSSION, AND AMERICA DESERVES
A DISCUSSION.
>> THIS HAS BEEN A TIPPING
POINT.
I THINK IT WAS SO GROTESQUE,
COMING ON THE BACK OF AURORA,
WHICH IN ITSELF WAS HORRIFYING
BEYOND BELIEF, A MOVIE THEATER,
NOW ELEMENTARY SCHOOL CHILDREN.
BARACK OBAMA AFTER BEING
REELECTED, HE HAS TO THINK OF A
LEGACY NOW.
DOES HE WANT HIS LEGACY TO BE A
SERIES OF FURTHER MASS SHOOTINGS
IN WHICH HE DID NOTHING.
BECAUSE THERE ARE GOING TO BE
MORE MASS SHOOTINGS.
THERE HAVE BEEN FOUR ALREADY IN
THE LAST FOUR YEARS OF
INCREASING APPALLING DETAIL.
THERE IS GOING TO BE WORSE.
>> I THINK THAT YOU'RE RIGHT IN
THE SENSE THAT EVERY CAUSE HAS
AN INFLECTION POINT.
AND THIS MAY BE THE INFLECTION
POINT FOR THE CAUSE OF PEOPLE
WHO WANT TO AT LEAST SEE A
REINSTATEMENT OF THE ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN.
BUT I THINK THAT WHAT WE HAVE TO
DO AS A SOCIETY, AND WHAT I HOPE
THE PRESIDENT WILL BE PREPARED
TO DO IS TO SAY WE HAVE TO START
ON -- START STOPPING THE
PROLIFERATION OF GUNS IN A
SOCIETY.
WHAT WE'RE FAST APPROACHING AT
THE MOMENT IS WHERE WE WILL HAVE
MORE GUNS IN THIS COUNTRY THAN
WE HAVE HUMAN BEINGS.
>> ACTUALLY, YOU HAVE ABOUT 300
MILLION GUNS IN CIRCULATION.
THE POPULATION IS --
>> 311, RIGHT.
>> HOW MANY CHILDREN.
>> RIGHT.
>> YOU ALREADY HAVE MORE GUNS
THAN THERE ARE ADULTS IN
AMERICA.
>> ACCORDING TO GALLUP, 45% OF
PEOPLE IN AMERICA SAY THEY HAVE
A GUN IN THEIR HOME THAT MEANS
MANY MORE PEOPLE HAVE MORE THAN
ONE GUN IN THEIR HOMES.
SEVEN OUT OF TEN PEOPLE SAY THEY
HAVE ACTUALLY FIRED A GUN THIS
THEIR LIFETIMES.
THAT MEANS WE AS A CULTURE ARE
GETTING TO A SATURATION POINT
FROM WHICH WE MAY NOT BE ABLE TO
PULL BACK.
AND WHAT IS HAPPENING AFTER
THESE SHOOTINGS, UNLIKE WHAT WE
WANT TO HAVE HAPPEN WHERE PEOPLE
SAY WE NEED TO DO SOMETHING
ABOUT THIS, WE NEED TO STOP
BUYING GUNS.
WHAT WE ARE -- BECAUSE WE DON'T
HAVE THE ADVOCATES ON THE OTHER
SIDE, FOR THE PEOPLE THAT SAY
YOU HAVE A RIGHT TO BEAR ARMS, I
ALSO HAVE A RIGHT TO NOT BEAR
ARMS, AND I SHOULD BE ABLE TO
FEEL SAFE.
WHO IS MY ADVOCATE WHO SAYS THAT
FOR THIS PERSON WHO DECIDES THAT
I DON'T WANT TO OWN A GUN, HOW
DO WE MAKE THAT PERSON FEEL SAFE
OR DOES THAT PERSON GET TO A
POINT WHERE THEY SAY BECAUSE 50,
60, WHATEVER IT GETS TO BE,
PERCENT OF THE POPULATION HAS A
GUN, I ACTUALLY NEED TO GET ONE
TO PROTECT MYSELF.
>> THE POINT IS THERE IS ALREADY
EXTENSIVE GUN CONTROL IN THE
COUNTRY.
THE GUN LOBBY MAKES OUT THIS
HIDEOUS NEW THING DESIGNED TO
SHACKLE THEM BUT THIS PARTICULAR
TYPE OF RIFLE IS NOW THE
PREFERRED MASS SHOOTER'S
INSTRUMENT OF DEVASTATING MURDER
AND THAT IS WHY IT HAS TO BE
TARGETED.
THE LAST THREE SHOOTINGS, THE
AR-15 WAS USED BECAUSE IT LOOKS
AS THE GUNN RIGHTS TOLD ME LIKE
THE FERRARI OF WEAPONS.
THIS HE HAVE TO TAKE IT OUT OF
CIRCULATION.
>> YOU DON'T SEE A LOT OF PEOPLE
COMMITTING THESE MASS SHOOTINGS
WITH REGULAR HUNTING RIFLES OR
MASS SHOOTINGS WITH REGULAR
REINVOLVERS.
THESE ARE SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPONS,
AND THERE IS A LOT OF CONFUSION.
A GUEST WAS SAYING THIS IS NOT
AN AUTOMATIC WEAPON.
YOU HAVE TO UNDERSTAND WHAT IT
DOES.
IT DOESN'T REQUIRE THE TRIGGER
GO -- THAT THE HAMMER GO ALL THE
WAY BACK AND YOU SQUEEZE AGAIN
REALLY HARD.
THE TRIGGERS ARE VERY SENSITIVE.
YOU JUST PULSE THE FINGER.
YOU CAN GET OFF THREE TO FIVE
ROUNDS IN ONE SECOND.
>> THERE IS A DIFFERENCE BETWEEN
THE POWER OF A AUTOMATIC AND THE
AR-15s IF THEY HAVE THE RIGHT
EQUIPMENT.
THAT'S THE REALITY.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
HT FROM US .
SO, I'M HAPPY.
SALES GO UP... I'M HAPPY.
IT WENT OUT TODAY... I'M HAPPY.
WHAT IF SHE'S NOT HOME?
(TOGETHER)
SHE WON'T BE HAPPY.
USE UPS! SHE CAN GET
A TEXT ALERT, REROUTE...
EVEN RESCHEDULE HER PACKAGE.
IT'S UPS MY CHOICE.
ARE YOU HAPPY?
I'M HAPPY.
HAPPY.
(TOGETHER)
I LOVE LOGISTICS.
SFX- "sounds of african
drum and flute"
Look who's back.
Again?
It's embarrassing
It's embarrassing!
We can see you Carl.
We can totally see you.
Come on you're better than
this...all that prowling around.
Yeah, you're the
king of the jungle.
Have you thought about going
vegan Carl?
HAHAHA!!
You know folks who save hundreds
of dollars by
switching to GEICO
sure are happy.
How happy are they Jimmy?
Happier than antelope with
night-vision goggles.
Nice!
Get happy. Get GEICO.
Fifteen minutes could save you
fifteen percent or more.
>>> SHE WAS THE TYPE OF PERSON
THAT COULD LIGHT UP A ROOM.
SHE ALWAYS HAD SOMETHING KIND
TO SAY ABOUT ANYBODY.
HER LOVE AND THE STRENGTH SHE
GAVE US AND THE EXAMPLE SHE
SHOWED US IS REMARKABLE.
SHE IS AN INCREDIBLE PERSON.
I AM SO BLESSED TO BE HER DAD.
>> SPEAKING OVER THE WEEKEND AND
I WANT TO THANK ALL OF MY GUESTS
FOR HE CAN HERE AND WE LEAVE YOU
POWERFUL WORDS FROM MR. PARKER.
HIS DAUGHTER WAS KILLED AT THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY AND HE
GAVE US A STATEMENT.
THANKING THOSE HE REACHED OUT TO
HELP THE FAMILIES AND HE WENT ON
TO SAY THIS, REMEMBER THE
BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN AND KEEP THEM
CLOSE TO OUR HEARTS AND DO NOT
LET THEIR BRIGHT SHANING FIESS
BECOME EXTINGUISHED.
LET US DO EVERYTHING IN OUR
POWER TO ENSURE THEIR LIGHT
CONTINUES TO SHINE BRIGHTER AND
BRIGHTER IN ALL THAT WE DO TO
REMEMBER THEM.
THAT'S ALL FOR US TONIGHT.
ñ?