>> I HAVE NO WORDS THAT MAKE THE
PAIN OF WHAT HAPPENED TODAY EASY
TO BEAR.
I'M HEARTBROKEN, AS I KNOW ALL
OF YOU ARE.
NOTHING MORE HURTFUL OR TRAGIC
THAN THE LOSS OF INNOCENCE, BUT
NO MORE SO WHEN THOSE LOST ARE
YOUNG CHILDREN.
I'M HEARTBROKEN.
>> PEOPLE'S CHILDREN, BROTHERS
AND SISTERS, WERE TAKEN FROM
THEM.
PEOPLE'S SPOUSES.
THOSE TEACHERS AND
ADMINISTRATORS WERE TAKEN FROM
US.
>> I HAVE TO COMMEND ALL OF THE
FIRST RESPONDERS, BOTH STATE AND
LOCAL, AND CERTAINLY THE STAFF
OF THE SCHOOL.
THEY WERE THERE FOR THOSE
CHILDREN, WHICH IS WHAT TEACHERS
ARE ALL ABOUT.
AND IT WAS MOST OBVIOUS TODAY,
MOST OBVIOUS TODAY, WHAT THEY
REALLY ARE ABOUT AS TEACHERS.
TO ALL OF THEM, I SAY THANKS ON
BEHALF OF ALL OF US.
>> AND THAT DOES IT FOR US.
THANK YOU FOR WATCHING.
ERIN BURNETT "OUTFRONT" STARTS
NOW.
>>> BREAKING NEWS, MASSACRE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
I'M ASHLEIGH BANFIELD IN FOR
ERIN BURNETT.
THIS JUST IN.
LISTEN.
>> 6-7 MUC.
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
CALLER THINKS SOMEONE IS
SHOOTING IN THE BUILDING.
FRONT GLASS IS BROKEN, UNSURE
WHY.
ALL UNITS, THE INDIVIDUAL THAT I
HAVE ON THE PHONE IS CONTINUING
TO HEAR WHAT HE BELIEVES TO BE
GUNFIRE.
UNITS RESPONDING SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL AT THIS TIME, THE
SHOOTING APPEARS TO HAVE
STOPPED.
THE SCHOOL IS IN LOCKDOWN.
>> THAT BROKEN GLASS IS THE
RESULT OF THE GUNMAN REPORTEDLY
SHOOTING HIS WAY INTO THE
SCHOOL.
THE UNTHINKABLE TRAGEDY HAS LEFT
THIS VERY SMALL NEW ENGLAND TOWN
SHATTERED TONIGHT.
28 PEOPLE DEAD.
THAT'S INCLUDING THE SHOOTER
HIMSELF.
MOST OF THOSE KILLED WERE
STUDENTS AT THE SCHOOL.
VERY, VERY YOUNG STUDENTS.
THERE WERE 20 CHILDREN KILLED.
BETWEEN THE AGES OF 5 AND 10
YEARS OLD.
THERE WERE ALSO 6 ADULTS SHOT
DEAD AFTER A HEAVILY ARMED
GUNMAN DRESSED IN BLACK FATIGUES
AND A MILITARY VEST OPENED FIRE
IN THE SCHOOL.
>> WE JUST TOLD A LITTLE BOY
ABOUT HIS SISTER NOW AND JUST TO
SEE HIM, HE SAID WHO AM I GOING
TO PLAY WITH?
I HAVE NOBODY TO PLAY WITH NOW.
EXCUSE ME.
>> THE GUNMAN, 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM
LANZA, ALSO DIED AT THE SCENE,
FROM A SELF-INFLICTED WOUND, HIS
MOTHER, NANCY LANZA FOUND DEAD
AT THE FAMILY HOME HERE IN
NEWTOWN AS WELL.
SHE HA HAD BEEN A TEACHER AT THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE SCHOOL'S PRINCIPAL, DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG AMONG THOSE KILLED.
AND A FRIEND REMEMBERS HER
TONIGHT AS THE KIND OF PERSON
YOU WANT EDUCATING YOUR KIDS.
AND THE GUNMAN'S OLDER BROTHER,
RYAN LANZA, TAKEN IN FOR
QUESTIONING BY POLICE IN HOBOKEN
IN NEW JERSEY AND HANDCUFFED.
OFFICIALS DID NOT LABEL HIM A
SUSPECT.
THE GUNMAN'S FATHER ALSO
QUESTIONED IN RELATION TO WHAT
HAPPENED HERE TODAY, AND
TONIGHT, A NATION IN MOURNING.
CANDLE-LIGHT VIGILS HELD IN
NEWTOWN AND ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
ALSO ONE JUST OUTSIDE THE
WITHOUT IN WASHINGTON, D.C.
EARLIER TODAY, PRESIDENT OBAMA
ORDERED FLAGS HALF STAFF
NATIONWIDE FOR THE VICTIMS OF
THE TRAGEDY.
IN AN EMOTIONAL ADDRESS, HE SAID
THIS TO THE NATION.
>> I KNOW THERE IS NOT A PARENT
IN AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS.
KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
>> AN EXTRAORDINARILY EMOTIONAL
PRESIDENT OBAMA EARLIER TODAY.
OBVIOUSLY, SO MANY QUESTIONS
THAT ARE EMERGING AFTER WHAT
HAPPENED TODAY.
A VIRTUAL MASSACRE OF LITTLE,
TINNY CHILDREN, AND THE WEAPONS
THAT WERE USED, NOTHING SHORT OF
TERRIFYING.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI FOLLOWING THIS
TODAY.
THREE DIFFERENT WEAPONS FOUND IN
DIFFERENT PLACES, VERY DANGEROUS
WEAPONS.
>> TWO WEAPONS FOUND ON THE
SHOOTERS HIMSELF, IN THE
CLASSROOM, WHERE HE WAS FOUND
DEAD.
ONE OF THEM IS A GLOCK, AND THE
OTHER IS A SIG SAUER, BOTH
HANDGUNS, A THIRD WEAPON FOUND
IN A CAR, A VEHICLE, MAY HAVE
BEEN HIS, OUTSIDE THE SCHOOL.
>> IS THAT THE SCHOOL BEEN
PARKED SO ERRATICALLY, ROPED OFF
WITH THE CRIME TAPE?
>> EXACTLY.
CLOSELY EXAMINING THAT CAR.
THE THIRD WEAPON A SEMI
AUTOMATIC KNOWN AS A
BUSHMASTER .223.
ALL OF THE WEAPONS BELONGED TO
HIS MOTHER.
A MOTHER, SCHOOL TEACHER AT THE
SCHOOL AND THEY WERE REGISTERED
IN THE STATE OF CONNECTICUT AS
WELL.
TRYING TO PIECE ALL OF THIS
TOGETHER, WHY DID THEY HAVE
THOSE GUNS.
HOW DID HE GET THEM?
>> JUST ONE AREA I KNOW WILL BE
A HUGE TOPIC OF CONVERSATION FOR
DAYS AND MONTHS TO COME.
ANOTHER BIG QUESTION FOR SO
MANY.
THE NAMES OF THESE CHILDREN.
THERE ARE 20 CHILDREN WHO DIED.
SIX ADULTS WHO DIED IN THE
SCHOOL.
NANCY, THE MOTHER WHO DIED IN
HER RESIDENCE.
WHEN WILL BE FIND OW THE OTHE O
IDENTITY OF VICTIMS?
>> TOMORROW MORNING.
THEY EXPECT TO RELEASE THE
IDENTITIES.
THEY HAVE BEEN WORKING VERY
DILIGENTLY TO CHECK, DOUBLE
CHECK, AND TRIPLE CHECK THEY
HAVE ALL OF THE RIGHT PEOPLE AND
THAT EVERYONE, MEMBERS OF THE
FAMILY HAVE BEEN NOTIFIED.
EXPECT TO HEAR THAT IN THE
MORNING.
>> SO SAD TO SEE BY EXCLUSION
THEY HAVE MADE THE IDENTITIES
OBVIOUS BY THOSE WHO WERE NOT
REUNITED WITH THE CHILDREN.
POSITIVE I.D.s, FORENSIC PROJECT
THAT WE WILL BE WORKING
THROUGHOUT THE NIGHT, WHERE THE
CHILDREN'S BODIES STILL LAY.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> SUSAN CANDIOTTI, THANK YOU,
WE APPRECIATE IT.
>> YOU BET.
>> AND DREW GRIFFIN WORKING ON
AS MUCH INFORMATION WE CAN FIND
ON THE SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA.
WHAT HAVE YOU FOUND OUT?
>> ACTUALLY, THIS IS PLAYING OUT
IN ALMOST A SICKENING ROUTINE.
A POSSIBLE MENTAL HEALTH ISSUE,
THE FAMILY TRYING TO DEAL WITH
THE MENTAL HEALTHISH EAUS.
SOMETHING SNAPS, GUNS EASILY
ACCESSIBLE AND THE SHOOTING
HAPPENS.
HERE IS WHAT WE KNOW.
THE 20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER HAD AN
OLDER BROTHER.
THAT BROTHER REPORTEDLY TOLD ABC
NEWS THAT THE SHOOTER, HIS
BROTHER, HAD A PERSONALITY
DISORDER.
HE ALSO MENTIONED HIS BROTHER
HAD AUTISM OR WAS AUTISTIC.
CNN HEARD THAT SAME INFORMATION
FROM A MAN WHO CALLED HIMSELF A
FRIEND IN NEWTOWN WHERE THE
SHOOTER LIVED.
ALREADY, WE'RE SEEING A KIND OF
BASE FOR SOME MENTAL HEALTH
QUESTIONS BEING RAISED,
ASHLEIGH.
>> DREW, JUST QUICKLY.
WHAT ABOUT WARNING SIGNS.
ANYBODY TALKING ABOUT WARNING
SIGNS?
>> NOT YET.
I FULLY EXPECT WE WILL SEE THAT
AND MORE DETAIL ON THAT.
RIGHT NOW, ALSO SOMEWHAT
STANDARD IN THESE CASES, ASHLEY,
YOU WILL FIND PEOPLE SHOCKED
THAT THIS PARTICULAR PERSON
COULD HAVE BEEN INVOLVED IN
ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
LISTEN TO WHAT WE HEARD IN THERE
A FORMER CLASSMATE AND SCHOOL
BUS DRIVER WHO KNEW THE
20-YEAR-OLD.
>> HE WAS JUST A KID.
>> JUST A KID?
>> JUST A KID.
>> NEVER ANTI SOCIAL?
>> NO.
ADAM HAS GOT A -- NO.
>> TROUBLE MAKER?
>> NO, DEFINITELY NOT.
>> NOTICEABLE?
JUST KIND OF BLEND INTO THE
BACKGROUND?
>> YEAH.
NOTHING THAT WOULD WARRANT ANY
OF THIS.
>> THEY ARE SAYING HE WENT AFTER
HIS MOM AND HER CLASS OF KIDS.
CAN YOU WRAP YOUR HEAD AROUND
THAT?
>> NO, I CANNOT.
I DON'T KNOW WHO WOULD DO
ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
>> SO YOUR GENERAL SENSE IS
WHAT?
>> THIS IS -- THIS IS
UNSPEAKABLE.
WHEN I FIRST HEARD ABOUT IT --
I'M STILL IN SHOCK.
EXCUSE ME A MOMENT.
I NEED TO GO.
>> A NICE KID.
VERY POLITELY.
SHE RAISED VERY NICE BOYS, TO
ME.
THAT'S WHY I THINK IT'S A SHOCK.
TO EVEN KNOW THEM AND REALIZE
WHO THEY ARE AND WHAT HE DID.
YOU CANNOT UNDERSTAND WHAT
HAPPENED, THAT HE SNAPPED, WHAT
HAVE YOU, AND TOOK SUCH INNOCENT
LIVES.
>> ASHLEIGH, I'M CONVINCED IN
THE COMING DAYS, MAYBE EVEN
TOMORROW, WE'LL BEGIN HEARING
THERE WERE WARNING SIGNS, THAT
THERE WERE MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES,
THERE WAS A FAMILY THAT DIDN'T
KNOW HOW TO HANDLE THE SITUATION
OR WHERE TO TURN, WE HAVE SEEN
IT AT THE SHOOTING AT VIRGINIA
TECH, GABY GIFFORDS, AURORA,
COLORADO, MOVIE THEATER.
I'M SURE WE'LL SEE THAT.
WHAT WE WILL NOT SEE, REALLY,
FOR THE FAMILIES, IS ANY KIND OF
EXPLANATION THAT WILL MAKE SENSE
OF THIS.
BECAUSE RIGHT NOW, IT'S
SENSELESS.
>> AND JUST SO UNBEARABLY
DIFFICULT TO DID I JUGEST, ESPE
HERE ON THE SCENE.
WITHOUT QUESTION, SOMETHING MUST
HAVE BEEN TERRIBLY WRONG.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
ONE NAME YOU WILL LIKELY BE
HEARING MORE OF, HER NAME IS
KAITLIN ROIG.
SHE IS BEING HAILED AS A HERO.
SHE SPOKE WITH DIANE SAWYER ON
"WORLD NEWS TONIGHT" EARLIER.
HAVE A LISTEN.
>> IN MY MIND, I'M THINKING, AS
A 6-YEAR-OLD, 7-YEAR-OLD, WHAT
ARE YOUR THOUGHTS?
AND I'M THINKING THAT I HAVE TO
ALMOST BE THEIR PARENT.
LIKE I HAVE TO TELL THEM, SO I
SAID TO THEM, I SAID I NEED YOU
TO KNOW THAT I LOVE YOU ALL VERY
MUCH.
AND THAT IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
BECAUSE I THOUGHT THAT WAS THE
LAST TIME THEY WERE EVER GOING
TO HEAR.
I THOUGHT WE WERE ALL GOING TO
DIE.
YOU KNOW, I DON'T KNOW IF THAT'S
OKAY.
YOU KNOW, TEACHERS AND, YOU
KNOW, I WANTED THEM TO KNOW
SOMEONE LOVED THEM AND I WANTED
THAT TO BE ONE OF THE LAST
THINGS THEY HEARD, NOT THE
GUNFIRE IN THE HALLWAY.
IT IS JUST SO HORRIBLE.
SO HORRIBLE.
>> INCREDIBLY EMOTIONAL STORY.
I'M JOINED BY THE HASKINS
FAMILY, BOB AND HIS CHILDREN,
JULIA AND BOBBY.
BOB, I WANT TO ASK YOU ABOUT A
FRIEND OF YOURS WHO IS A
BASKETBALL COACH HERE IN TOWN,
WHO HAS TWO CHILDREN ATTENDING
SANDY HOOK.
ONE OF THOSE CHILDREN WAS A
FIRST GRADER WHO WITNESSED
SOMETHING ABSOLUTELY
UNBELIEVABLE.
I WANT YOU TO RECOUNT FOR ME THE
STORY IF YOU WILL.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
JUST SPOKE TO HIM AN HOUR OR SO
AGO.
HIS YOUNG SON WAS IN CLASS, AND
THE SHOOTER BROKE INTO THE
CLASSROOM, FRONT OF HIS EYES
GUNNED DOWN THE TEACHER, HE WAS
ASTUTE TO TAKE A COUPLE OF
STUDENTS AND RAN OUT THE DOOR
BEHIND THE BACK OF THE SHOOTER
AND RAN OUT OF THE SCHOOL AND
CONTINUED TO RUN FOR ABOUT A
HALF A MILE UNTIL HE HIT THE
MAIN ROAD.
A STRANGER PICKED UP THE KIDS
AND TOOK THEM TO THE NEWTOWN
POLICE DEPARTMENT.
UNBEKNOWNST TO THE PARENTS, WHEN
THEY WENT TO TALK TO THE STATE
TROOPERS AND PARENTS, HER SON
WAS UNACCOUNTED FOR.
GO DOOR TO DOOR, LOOK IN THE
WOODS, AND FOR AN HOUR OR SO,
THEY HAD NO IDEA WHERE THEIR SON
WAS.
THEY CALLED THE POLICE
DEPARTMENT A COUPLE OF TIMES,
HAD NO RECORD OF HIM BEING THERE
AND FINALLY AFTER ABOUT AN HOUR
AND A HALF, THEY CALLED AND
RELIEVED TO FIND OUT, INDEED,
THEIR SON HAD BEEN DROPPED OFF
AT THE POLICE DEPARTMENT SAFE
AND SOUND.
>> BUT AT THAT TIME, THEY MUST
HAVE THOUGHT THE WORST.
>> THEY THOUGHT THE WORST.
IT WAS VERY, VERY DIFFICULT TIME
FOR THEM.
HE SAID IT WAS THE WORST HOUR
AND A HALF HE'S EVER EXPERIENCED
IN HIS LIFE.
>> POLICE INTERVIEWED THIS FIRST
GRADER.
I'M GUESSING HE'S 6, 7 YEARS
OLD.
>> 6 YEARS OLD.
THEY INTERVIEWED HIM SINCE HE
WAS THERE.
>> WHAT DID HE TELL THEM, WHAT
KIND OF DETAIL?
>> THE INTERVIEW, VERY
ELEMENTARY.
THEY ASKED WHAT HE SAW.
DESCRIBED THE SHOOTER, HIS FACE,
EXPRESSION.
THEY ASKED WHAT WAS HIS
RECOLLECTION OF THE ROOM.
HE SAID I SAW A WHOLE BUNCH OF
SILVER BULLETS ON THE FLOOR OF
THE CLASSROOM, WHEN I GOT INTO
THE HALL, I SAW A WHOLE BUNCH OF
BULLETS ON THE FLOOR, AND THIS
WEREN'T SILVER, THEY WERE RED,
UNFORTUNATELY, COVERED WITH
BLOOD IN THE HALLWAY.
AND AT THAT POINT, HE RAN,
SPRINTED OUT OF THE SCHOOL.
>> DID HE GIVE A DESCRIPTION ANY
FURTHER ABOUT THE SHOOTER, THE
FACE, DID HE SAY ANYTHING?
ANYTHING LIKE THAT?
>> HE DESCRIBED WHAT HE LOOKED
LIKE.
BUT IT'S A VERY ELEMENTARY CITY
DESCRIPTION BECAUSE HE'S 6 YEARS
OLD.
>> JULIA, YOU ARE -- HAVE YOU A
DIFFERENT STORY.
YOU'RE IN THE MIDDLE SCHOOL HERE
IN TOWN.
YOU WENT INTO LOCKDOWN RIGHT
AWAY AS SOON AS THIS HAPPENED.
>> YES.
>> DID YOU KNOW WHAT WAS
HAPPENING?
EVERYBODY HAS CELL PHONES AND
MIGHT HAVE BEEN TEXT MESSAGES,
DID YOU KNOW WHAT WAS GOING ON?
>> NO CLUE WHAT WAS GOING ON
UNTIL THE FIRST HOUR.
ONE OF THE MY TEACHERS SAID
THERE WAS A SHOOTING A MILE DOWN
THE ROAD.
>> DO YOU HAVE A CLASSMATE WHO
HAD A LITTLE BROTHER AT THE
SCHOOL?
>> YES.
THE BOY WHO I WAS SITTING RIGHT
NEXT TO DURING THE LOCKDOWN, HIS
LITTLE BROTHER ENDED UP DYING.
>> HOW DID HE FIND THAT OUT?
>> I'M NOT EXACTLY SURE.
I HAVEN'T TALKED TO HIM YET
TODAY, DURING THE LOCKDOWN, HE
DIDN'T SAY ANYTHING.
I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW HE HAD A
LITTLE BROTHER AT SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL UNTIL I JUST FOUND OUT
HIS BROTHER HAD DIED.
>> HE HADN'T BEEN CONCERNED AT
THE TIME ABOUT FINDING OUT THE
FATE OF HIS LITTLE BROTHER WHILE
HE WAS IN LOCKDOWN IN YOUR
CLASSROOM?
>> IT DIDN'T SEEM LIKE IT, NO.
>> BOBBY, YOU WERE IN ANOTHER
SCHOOL AS WELL.
HAND THIS OFF TO YOU.
YOU WERE IN ANOTHER SCHOOL, YOU
WENT INTO LOCKDOWN.
WHAT WAS THE EXPERIENCE FOR YOU?
>> IT WAS A LITTLE DIFFERENT.
WE WERE IN CHURCH AT THE TIME.
FRIDAY SCHOOL MASS AND MONSIGNOR
WISE CAME IN, WE NEED TO END
MASS DOWN AND GO TO IMMEDIATE
LOCKDOWN.
WHAT HAPPENED, THE TEACHERS WENT
AROUND, LOCKED ALL THE DOORS AND
WE SAT IN THE PEWS AND JUST
WAITED AND WE COULD HEAR SIRENS
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR.
>> DID YOU LIKE YOUR SISTER
EVENTUALLY FIND OUT WHAT WAS
GOING ON?
>> YEAH, WE -- EVENTUALLY WENT
BACK TO THE SCHOOL, AND THEN MY
CLASS WAS LOCKED DOWN IN THE
BASEMENT, AND OUR TEACHERS TOLD
US THAT THERE HAD BEEN A
SHOOTING AND THERE WERE
FATALITIES, BUT I DIDN'T KNOW
THE SERIOUSNESS OF IT UNTIL MY
DAD PICKED ME UP EARLY FROM
SCHOOL, AND ON THE CAR RIDE
HOME, HE TOLD ME THERE ARE QUITE
A FEW FATALITIES?
>> ARE YOU OKAY?
>> WE WENT TO THE VIGIL TONIGHT
AT 7:00.
IT WAS VERY EMOTIONAL.
>> YOU ARE AWFULLY YOUNG TO
DIGEST THIS.
NONE OF US ARE HANDLING THIS
WELL.
>> IT DIDN'T REALLY SINK IN.
I WAS NUMB UP UNTIL -- UNTIL THE
VIGIL AND I THINK I KIND OF
BROKE DOWN AT THE VIGIL, BECAUSE
IT WAS SO SAD TO SEE EVERYONE
THERE AND SEE -- THEY HAD
ACTUALLY 28 CANDLES ON THE ALTAR
TO REPRESENT THE VICTIMS.
>> AT THE VIGIL.
AND PASS THE MIKE TO YOUR DAD.
BOB, AN INCREDIBLE MOMENT AT THE
VIGIL, THERE WAS A LETTER THAT
WAS READ FROM THE POPE.
>> THERE WAS A LETTER THAT WAS
WROTE -- THAT WAS WRITTEN BY
POPE BENEDICT TO OUR COMMUNITY
SPECIFICALLY, WHICH WAS VERY
TOUCHING.
AND VERY MEANINGFUL.
IT MEANT A GREAT DEAL TO THE
WHOLE COMMUNITY, AND ON TOP OF
THAT, WHAT WAS REALLY EMOTIONAL
FOR US, MONSIGNOR WISE, A
WONDERFUL PASTOR OF OUR CHURCH
TALKED ABOUT IN HIS HOMILY, THE
TIME HE SPENT WITH THE 20
FAMILIES TODAY, AND IN
PARTICULAR HE MENTIONED TWO
LITTLE ANGELS BEING ONE OF WHOM
THE MOTHER OF THE VICTIM SAID
SHE WENT OUT RECENTLY AND GOT
HER FIRST COMMUNE DRESS, AND THE
DAUGHTER WAS VERY, VERY EXCITED
ABOUT THAT.
AND THE OTHER LITTLE ANGEL WAS
GOING TO PLAY AN ANGEL IN OUR
SCHOOL PLAY AT ST. ROSE NEXT
WEEK.
A VERY POIGNANT STORY AND VERY,
VERY EMOTIONAL FOR US TO HEAR
AND DIGEST.
>> HOW IS YOUR FRIEND?
THE BASKETBALL COACH WHOSE CHILD
WENT THROUGH THIS HARROWING
ORDEAL, HOW IS HE DOING?
>> I THINK BEST WAY TO DESCRIBE
IT, TRAUMATIZED.
A WONDERFUL MAN, WONDERFUL
PERSON, WONDERFUL FAMILY, AND
ALTHOUGH HE'S INCREDIBLY
GRATEFUL, YOU KNOW, THAT HIS SON
IS SAFE, HIS HEART IS CERTAINLY
BLEEDING FOR THE OTHER CHILDREN
IN THE CLASSROOM, BECAUSE TWO OF
HIS SON'S CLASSMATES DID PERISH
IN THAT SAGA THAT I TOLD YOU,
WHEN THE GUNMAN CAME IN.
TWO OF THE LITTLE BOYS
CLASSMATE'S WERE KILLED TODAY.
>> AND HE WITNESSED.
>> HE WITNESSED IT.
>> HE WITNESSED HIS OWN TEACHER
BEING SHOT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
AND OUR HEARTS GO OUT TO ALL OF
YOU HERE.
THE NATION IS IN MOURNING WITH
EVERYBODY HERE IN NEWTOWN.
I HOPE ARE YOU GOING TO BE OKAY.
HUG YOUR KIDS TIGHT.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> COMING UP NEXT, THE HASKINS
FAMILY TOUCHED ON THE VIGIL AND
THE VERY SPECIAL MESSAGE THAT
CAME FROM HALFWAY AROUND THE
WORLD.
THE GOVERNOR WAS HERE, THE
SENATORS WERE HERE.
WE'LL GIVE YOU A BETTER FEEL FOR
EXACTLY WHAT IT WAS LIKE INSIDE
THE CHURCH, LATER ON.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
>>> THIS IS A COMMUNITY OF
27,000 PEOPLE.
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, IT IS
QUIET, IT IS SPACIOUS.
THERE ARE HALCYON AREAS WHERE
TREES STRETCH BETWEEN HOUSES,
AND YET IT'S STILL A CLOSE TOWN
AND PEOPLE KNOW EACH OTHER AND
THEY NEEDED SOMETHING, ANYTHING,
TO TRY TO COME TOGETHER AFTER
THE HORRORS THAT THEY WERE
FORCED TO ENDURE TODAY.
THE FACT THAT SO MANY OF THEIR
CHILDREN WIIN THIS COMMUNITY WI
NO LONGER BE WITH THEM.
THEY GATHERED AT A CATHOLIC
CHUR
CHURCH, ST. ROSE OF LIMA.
YOU WERE THERE FOR THE VIGIL
TONIGHT.
JASON CARROLL, IT WAS STANDING
ROOM ONLY?
>> BEYOND THAT.
HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE OUTSIDE HERE,
ASHLEIGH, WHO COULDN'T GET
INSIDE.
THEY CAME OUT HERE, THEY WANTED
SOMETHING, ANYTHING, LEANING ON
EACH OTHER AND THEY LEANED ON
THEIR FAITH AND THEY CAME OUT
TODAY, NO QUESTION ABOUT IT.
SPOKE TO A DEACON HERE,
EXPLAINED IT, AND SAID WHEN YOU
HAVE A COMMUNITY THIS CLOSE IT
SHOULD COME AS NO SURPRISE,
HUNSDS
HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE OUT HERE,
MOST PEOPLE KNEW SOMEONE.
IF IT WASN'T A PARENT IT WAS A
CHILD.
IF IT WASN'T A CHILD, IT WAS A
TEACHER.
IF IT WASN'T A TEACHER, IT WAS
AN ADMINISTRATOADMINISTRATOR.
THEY CAME FOR COMFORTING WORDS
FROM MONSIGNOR ROBERT WISE.
WHO READ A LETTER FROM THE POPE.
>> I CONHAVE A MY HEARTFELT
GRIEF AND THE ASSURANCE OF MY
PERSONAL PRAYERS TO THE VICTIMS
AND THEIR FAMILIES.
TO ALL OF THOSE AND THE
COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN AND
ESPECIALLY THE PARISH OF ST.
ROSE OF LIMA, IN THE AFTERMATH
OF THE SENSELESS TRAGEDY, I ASK
GOD OUR FATHER TO CONSOLE ALL OF
THOSE WHO MOURN, AND TO SUSTAIN
THE ENTIRE COMMUNITY WITH THE
SPIRITUAL STRENGTH WHICH
TRIUMPHS OVER VIOLENCE WITH THE
POWER OF FORGIVENESS, HOPE, AND
RECONCILING LOVE.
>> AND, ASHLEIGH, ONE OF THE
DEACONS AT THE CHURCH.
HE SAID THROUGHOUT THE DAY HE
HAD RECEIVED ALMOST 100 PEOPLE
WHO HAD COME THROUGH CHURCH
DOORS LOOKING FOR SOMETHICOMFOR
LOOKING FOR ANSWERS, MANY ASKING
WHY.
AND I TOLD THEM SOMETIMES THERE
ARE NO ANSWERS, SOMETIMES IT'S
JUST TOO SOON.
MAYBE THIS IS ONE THAT ONLY GOD
CAN ANSWER.
>> JASON, ONE OF THE SIX ADULTS
KILLED WAS THE SCHOOL'S
PRINCIPAL, DAWN HOCHSPRUNG.
HAVE YOU LEARNED MORE ABOUT HER?
>> WE ARE HEARING SO MUCH ABOUT
HER.
47 YEARS OLD.
TWO DAUGHTERS, THREE
STEPDAUGHTERS.
SHE HAS BEEN THE PRINCIPAL AT
SANDY HOOK SINCE JUNE 2010.
CONSTANTLY TWITTERING, SO PROUD
OF HER SCHOOL.
TWITTERING ABOUT FOURTH GRADERS
JUST THIS WEEK.
FROM ALL ACCOUNTS, ASHLEIGH, SHE
WAS A WOMAN WHO LOVED HER
SCHOOL, LOVED HER STUDENTS,
LOVERED HER JOBS, WE TALKED
ABOUT THAT CLOSE COMMUNITY, NO
SURPRISE TO FIND A MAN OUT HERE
TODAY, WHO KNEW HER, KNEW HER
WELL.
AND HE WANTS YOU TO HEAR WHAT HE
HAD TO SAY ABOUT HER.
>> DAWN, I HAD DINNER WITH HER
LAST SPRING, SHE WAS EXCITING,
EXUBERANT, AND A GREAT EDUCATOR.
IT'S SAD, THEY LOST A LEADER
TODAY AT SANDY HOOK.
MY PRAYERS WILL BE, YOU KNOW,
FOR OUR COMMUNITY AS WELL.
>> AGAIN, AS YOU HEARD, LOST A
LEADER HERE, AND DEALING WITH
THIS LOSS, DEALING WITH THE
PAIN, DEALING WITH THE
SUFFERING, AND THIS IS WHAT THIS
COMMUNITY IS GOING TO COPE WITH
FROM THIS POINT ON.
FOR DAYS, WEEKS, MONTHS, AND
CERTAINLY FOR THE PARENTS OF
THOSE CHILDREN, NO SAYING HOW
LONG THEY WILL BE DEALING WITH
THEIR GRIEF.
ASHLEIGH.
>> AND SO DISTRESSING, JASON, TO
KNOW THAT PRINCIPAL JUST THIS
FALL IMPLEMENTED A BRAND NEW
SECURITY SYSTEM WHERE YOU HAD TO
GET BUZZED IN AT 9:30 IN THE
MORNING, AND YET THIS WAS
PERPETRATED AGAINST HER SCHOOL.
JASON CARROLL, REPORTING LIVE
JUST ACROSS TOWN FROM WHERE I
AM.
PART OF THE REASON I AM WHERE I
AM, IS THAT THE MEDIA IS GETTING
REGULAR UPDATES AT THIS
LOCATION, NOT ONLY FROM THE
STATE POLICE, BUT ALSO FROM
CONNECTICUT'S GOVERNOR DAN
MALLOY, WHO HAS COME AT REGULAR
INTERVALS TO BRIEF US, BUT ALSO
SPOKEN WITH THE FAMILIES WHO
WERE GIVEN THE ULTIMATE TERRIBLE
NEWS THEY WOULD NOT BE REUNITING
WITH THEIR CHILDREN.
HE MADE ANOTHER STOP AT THE
VIGIL JASON REPORTED ON.
>> GOOD EVENING, EVERYONE.
MONSIGNOR, THANK YOU VERY MUCH
FOR OPENING THIS VERY BEAUTIFUL
CHURCH SO THAT WE MIGHT IN A
COMMUNAL WAY FIND SOLACE AND ONE
ANOTHER AS A RESULT OF THE
UNSPEAKABLE HAVING OCCURRED IN
THIS COMMUNITY.
PEOPLE'S CHILDREN, BROTHERS,
SISTERS, WERE TAKEN FROM THEM.
PEOPLE'S SPOUSES.
THOSE TEACHERS AND
ADMINISTRATORS, WERE TAKEN FROM
US.
YET WE STAND IN A CHURCH AND
MANY OF US TODAY, IN THE COMING
DAYS, WILL RELY UPON THAT WHICH
WE HAVE BEEN TAUGHT AND THAT
WHICH WE INHERENTLY BELIEVE THAT
THERE IS FAITH FOR A REASON AND
THAT FAITH ITSELF IS GOD'S GIFT
TO ALL OF YOU.
AND IN THESE TIMES OF TROUBLES
AND TRAVAILS, WHEN THE
UNTHINKABLE HAPPENS IN OUR VERY
MIDST, OUR FAITH IS TESTED.
NOT JUST IN THE RELIGIOUS SENSE,
NOT JUST NECESSARILY OUR FAITH
IN GOD, BUT OUR FAITH IN
COMMUNITY, IN WHO WE ARE, IN
WHAT WE COLLECTIVELY OFFER.
AND IN SO MANY WAYS, PERMISSIBLE
TO HAVE THOSE THOUGHTS AND THOSE
DOUBTS ABOUT WHO WE ARE, WHAT WE
ARE, WHAT COMMUNITY REPRESENTS,
BUT THEN WE TURN TO UNDERSTAND
AS WE TURN AROUND THIS ROOM AND
RECOGNIZE OUR FRIENDS AND OUR
NEIGHBORS.
THOSE WE HAVE DONE THINGS FOR,
AND THOSE WHO HAVE DONE THINGS
FOR US.
THIS IS A GREAT AND BEAUTIFUL
COMMUNITY LOCATED IN A GREAT AND
BEAUTIFUL STATE IN A GREAT AND
BEAUTIFUL NATION.
IN THE COMING DAYS, THE COMING
WEEKS, I WILL PRAY THAT YOU ALL
EMBRACE ONE ANOTHER.
THAT YOU LIFT ONE ANOTHER UP.
THAT YOU UNDERSTAND THE
DIFFICULTIES THAT YOU
COLLECTIVELY WILL UNDERGO.
KEEP IN YOUR PRAYERS THE
CHILDREN WHO LAST THEIR LIVES
TODAY.
KEEP IN YOUR PRAYERS THE ADULTS
WHO LOST THEIR LIVES TODAY.
AND UNDERSTAND THAT A TEST IS
JUST THAT.
THAT WHICH WE RISE TO AND ANSWER
AND RESPOND TO.
IN THE COMING DAYS AS MANY OF US
PREPARE TO CELEBRATE THE BIRTH
OF CHRIST, UNDERSTAND THAT THAT
TO WILL BRING SORROW AS WE THINK
ABOUT THESE INSTANCES THAT HAVE
HAPPENED SO CLOSE TO THOSE DAYS.
BUT THAT TOO WILL PASS AND BE
OVERCOME.
AND ALL OF OUR PRAYERS AND THE
PRAYERS AND HOPES OF ALL OF THE
PUBLIC OFFICIALS WHO HAVE
ASSEMBLED TODAY AND IN THE
PRESENCE OF YOUR GREAT COLLECT
PERSON, I BRING AND EXTEND THE
ENTIRE CONDOLENCES TO YOU,
MEMBERS OF THIS COMMUNITY.
MAY GOD BLESS YOU.
MY GOD BLESS OUR CHILDREN WHO
ARE WITH US TODAY AND THOSE WHO
WERE TAKEN AWAY.
AND GOD BLESS THE ADULTS WHO
LOST THEIR LIVES TODAY.
THANK YOU.
>> I WANTED TO SHARE WITH YOU
ONE OF THE MORE POIGNANT STORIES
THAT I LEARNED TODAY FROM A
NURSE NAMED MAUREEN.
SHE WANTED TO VOLUNTEER.
WHEN SHE HEARD WHAT WAS GOING ON
AT THE SCHOOL, SHE AND ANOTHER
NURSE RACED TO THE SCHOOL TO
HELP AND FOUND THEMSELVES
SURPRISED THAT THERE WAS NOTHING
FOR THEM TO DO.
SADLY, THEY BEGAN TO UNDERSTAND
THAT THERE WERE NO MORE
SURVIVORS COMING OUT OF THE
SCHOOL.
THEY MADE THEIR WAY TO THE FIRE
STATION, A STAGING AREA FOR
PATIENTS TO BE REUNITED WITH
THEIR KIDS, AND, OF COURSE, IT
WAS A STAGING AREA WHERE A LOT
OF PARENTS WOULDN'T BE REUNITED
WITH THEIR CHILDREN EITHER.
THE SAD STORY THAT SHE TOLD ME
WAS THE MOMENT THAT,
UNFORTUNATELY, THE AUTHORITIES
HAD TO TELL THESE PARENTS THAT
THERE WERE NO MORE SURVIVORS.
ANOTHER WITNESS, WHO WAS IN THE
AREA SAID THAT THE CRIES AND THE
WAILS WERE OVERWHELMING, THAT IT
WAS ONE OF THE MORE DIFFICULT
THINGS TO HAVE TO UNDERGO.
TWO PRIESTS WHO WERE ON THE
SCENE AS WELL, AT LEAST TWO
GRIEF COUNSELOR THERE TO TRY TO
HANDLE WHAT WAS GOING TO HAPPEN
WITH THESE APPROXIMATELY 50
PEOPLE.
YOU THINK ABOUT IT, 20 KIDS, AND
THEY ALL HAVE PARENTS, SO
ROUGHLY 50 PEOPLE HAD TO ENDURE
THAT TERRIBLE MOMENT, WHEN THEY
WERE TOLD THEY WOULD LIKELY
NEVER SEE THEIR CHILDREN AGAIN.
COMING UP, A WOMAN WHO WORKS AT
A DAYCARE HERE IN TOWN TELLS US
THAT MANY OF HER DAYCARE
STUDENTS HAD GRADUATED TO BECOME
STUDENTS AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
SHE'LL TALK TO US IN A MOMENT.
ME...
thinking my only option was the
vial and syringe dad used.
And ME...
discovering once-daily
Levemir® FlexPen.
FlexPen® is prefilled.
Doesn't need
refrigeration
for up to
42 days.
No drawing from a vial.
Dial the exact dose.
Inject by pushing a button.
FlexPen® is insulin delivery...
MY way.
is a long-acting insulin
used to control high blood sugar
in adults and children
with diabetes and is not
recommended to treat
diabetic ketoacidosis.
Do not use Levemir® if
you are allergic
to any of its ingredients.
The most common side effect
is low blood sugar,
which may cause
symptoms such as sweating,
shakiness, confusion,
and headache.
Severe low blood sugar can be
serious and life threatening.
Ask your healthcare provider
about alcohol use,
operating machinery, or driving.
Other possible side
effects include
injection site reactions.
Tell your healthcare provider
about all medicines you take
and all of your
medical conditions.
Get medical help right away
if you experience
serious allergic
reactions, such as body rash,
trouble with breathing, fast
heartbeat, or sweating.
With FlexPen®... say good night
to vial and syringe.
Ask your doctor about
Levemir® FlexPen.
Covered by
90% of insurance plans,
including Medicare.
Find your co-pay at
MyFlexPen.com.
WE DON'T LET FREQUENT HEARTBURN
COME BETWEEN US
AND WHAT WE LOVE.
SO IF YOU'RE ONE OF THEM PEOPLE
WHO GETS HEARTBURN
AND THEN TREATS DAY AFTER DAY...
BLOCK THE ACID WITH PRILOSEC OTC
AND DON'T GET HEARTBURN
IN THE FIRST PLACE!
[ Male Announcer ]
ONE PILL EACH MORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBURN.
>>> LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, TONIGHT, IN A STORY
THAT OVERWHELMED MANY PEOPLE AS
IT BEGAN TO UNFOLD.
A STORY WE'VE OFTEN COVERED
BEFORE.
SHOTS MAY HAVE RUNG OUT AT A
SCHOOL.
BUT AS DETAILS ROLLED IN AND THE
MAGNITUDE OF THIS HORROR
UNFOLDED, IT WAS ASTOUNDING, THE
SHEER NUMBERS INVOLVED.
HERE IS HOW THE DAY PLAYED OUT.
WE ARE FOLLOWING THIS REPORT
THAT THERE HAS BEEN A SHOOTING
AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL NAMED SANDY
HOOK.
>> THE INTERCOM CAME ON AT THE
SCHOOL, AND SHE HEARD A SCREAM,
AND A GUNSHOT.
TWO GUNSHOTS.
>>  TROOPERS TO THE
SCHOOL AND IMMEDIATELY UPON
ARRIVAL BEGAN TO THE SCHOOL AND
BEGAN A COMPLETE ACTIVE SHOOTERS
SEARCH OF THE BUILDING.
>> THEY HAD TO HIDE IN THE
CLOSET, AND THE CHILDREN WERE
VERY SHAKEN, CRYING IN THE
CLOSET.
>> I SAW SOME OF THE BULLETS
GOING PAST THE HALL, THEN A
TEACHER PULLED ME INTO HER
CLASSROOM.
>> THE POLICE CAME IN.
IT'S LIKE IS HE IN HERE?
THEN HE RAN OUT, AND OUR
TEACHER, AND SOMEBODY YELLED GET
TO A SAFE PLACE.
>> I HEARD THE PRINCIPAL SHOT
AND KILLED.
I HEARD -- I HEARD SOME KIDS
WERE SHOT.
A TEACHER, MRS. HAMMONDS WAS
SHOT.
>> 18 CHILDREN PRONOUNCED DEAD
AT THE SCHOOL.
TWO TRANSPORTED TO AREA
HOSPITALS AND PRONOUNCED DEAD AT
AREA HOSPITALS AND SIX
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCENE.
>> WE TOLD A LITTLE BOY ABOUT
HIS SISTER, AND IT'S SO HARD.
HE SAID I HAVE NOBODY TO PLAY
WITH NOW.
BUT -- EXCUSE ME.
>> THE PERPETRATOR OF THE CRIME
IS DEAD.
AS IS AN INDIVIDUAL WHO THE
PERPETRATOR LIVED WITH.
>> RYAN LANZA BEING TAKEN INTO
CUSTODY TODAY IN HOBOKEN.
RYAN LANZA NOT CHARGES WITH
ANYTHING TODAY.
AT THIS POINT HE IS BEING
QUESTIONED.
>> THERE IS A RELATED SCENE THAT
WE DISCOVERED AS WE CONTINUED
OUR CRIMINAL INVESTIGATION.
>> I ASK GOD OUR FORTHER TO
CONSOLE THOSE WHO MOURN AND
SUSTAIN THE ENTIRE COMMUNITY
WITH THE STRENGTH WHICH TRIUMPHS
OVER VIOLENCE WITH THE POWER OF
FORGIVENESS, HOPE, AND
RECONCILING LOVE.
>> THIS WAS THE SECOND DEADLIEST
SCHOOL SHOOTING IN AMERICAN
HISTORY.
20 YOUNG CHILDREN LOTT LOST
THELOST
THEIR LIVES, AGES 5 TO 10.
THE REST OF THE CLASSMATES WERE
ROBBED OF INNOCENCE AFTER
WITNESSING THIS TRAGEDY, THESE
PARENTS WILL FOREVER BE
MOURNING.
I WANT TO INTRODUCE TO YOU
MICHELLE BABCO.
SHE USED TO WORK AT A DAYCARE
AND WATCHED MANY OF THE CHILDREN
THAT WERE IN THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AT THE TIME OF THE
SHOOTING.
HOW DID YOU FIND OUT ABOUT THE
SHOOTING?
>> EARLIER THIS AFTERNOON, I
CONTACTED A FAMILY AND ASKED IF
THE GIRLS WERE OKAY.
THEY WERE HOME SAFE AND SOUND,
BUT TO PRAY FOR THE ONES THAT
WERE VERY FORTUNAUNFORTUNATE.
>> DO YOU KNOW IF ANY OF THE
KIDS WHO ATTENDED YOUR DAYCARE
WERE VICTIMS OF THE RAMPAGE?
>> ALL OF THEM RIGHT NOW HOME
SAFE AND SOUND WITH THEIR
FAMILIES.
>> IT MUST BE AN ENORMOUS
RELIEF?
>> IT WAS.
TO HEAR ALL OF THE KIDS I HAVE
KEPT IN TOUCH WITH ALL THESE
YEARS WERE HOME, YES.
>> DID YOU HAVE A CHANCE TO TALK
TO THEIR PARENTS OR FIND OUT HOW
THEY ARE DOING?
>> I DID.
I SAID THEY ARE VERY FORTUNATE,
HOME, AND, YOU KNOW, TO PRAY FOR
THE ONES THAT WERE NOT SO
FORTUNATE IN THE SHOOTING
EARLIER TODAY.
AND VERY, VERY HAPPY THAT THEIR
LITTLE ONES ARE HOME SAFE AND
SOUND.
>> YOU WORK AT THE DAYCARE, THE
LITTLE EXPLORERS DAYCARE.
>> YES.
>> ARE YOU CLOSED?
ARE YOU GOING TO BE ABLE TO KEEP
WORKING ON MONDAY?
IS ANYTHING CHANGING IN TERMS OF
YOUR SECURITY MEASURES?
HOW WILL THIS AFFECT YOU AS YOU
GO FORWARD, LOOKING AFTER YOUR
LITTLE ONES?
>> I WORKED THERE SEVERAL YEARS
AGO, BUT IT IS UP AND RUNNING AS
OF TODAY.
>> IT IS RUNNING?
>> IT IS.
>> YOU ALSO HAVE A FRIEND WHO IS
A TEACHER AT THE SCHOOL.
>> YES.
I FOUND OUT THAT SHE WAS INJURED
EARLIER TODAY AND LAST TIME I
SPOKE TO THE FAMILY THAT KEEPS
IN TOUCH WITH HER, SHE WAS STILL
IN THE HOSPITAL.
>> HOW WAS SHE INJURED?
>> SHE WAS SHOT IN THE FOOT.
>> DO YOU KNOW IF SHE WAS IN
THAT MEETING WHEREBY THE
PRINCIPAL AND THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST WERE SHOT DEAD?
THERE WAS A REPORT THAT THREE OF
THESE TEACHERS IN THE MEETING
HAD EMERGED INTO THE HALLWAY
WHEN THE GUNSHOTS RANG OUT AND
ONLY ONE CAME BACK AND WAS
INJURED IN THE FOOT OR THE LEG
AND I'M TRYING TO PUT TOGETHER
WHETHER IT MIGHT HAVE BEEN YOUR
FRIEND?
>> IT MIGHT HAVE BEEN THE SAME
PERSON, I'M UNCERTAIN OF THAT.
I KNOW SHE WAS SHOT IN THE FOOT.
>> HOW ARE YOU PROCESSING THIS?
>> IT'S HARD TO HANEL THIS, I
HAD ALL OF THESE KIDS SINCE THEY
WERE THREE.
I KEEP IN TOUCH WITH THE
FAMILIES AND JUST VERY THANKFUL
THAT THEY ARE HOME ON THIS
HOLIDAY WITH THEIR PARENTS, BUT
STILL PRAYING FOR THE ONES THAT
WERE INJURED.
>> AND NEWTOWN, SUCH A BEAUTIFUL
AND QUIET COMMUNITY.
EVERYONE WHO GOES THROUGH A
TRAGEDY SAYS IT WOULD NEVER
OCCUR THAT IT WOULD HAPPEN
THERE.
AND IT CERTAINLY DOESN'T OCCUR
THAT IT WOULD HAPPEN HERE.
>> IT COULD HAPPEN ANYWHERE.
IT'S SMALL, QUAINT, AND QUIET,
BUT IT'S UNFORTUNATE THAT IT DID
HAPPEN.
>> YOU AND YOUR NEIGHBORS GOING
TO BE OKAY?
>> YES, HOME WITH MY PARENTS.
WE'LL BE OKAY.
>> THANK YOU FOR TALKING WITH
US.
GOOD LUCK TO YOU AS WELL.
>> THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I WANT TO GO BACK TO MY
COLLEAGUES, DREW GRIFFIN.
A NUMBER OF WEAPONS THAT WERE
RECOVERED AT THE SCHOOL.
ALL OF THEM.
ALL THREE OWNED BY THE SHOOTER'S
MOTHER.
REGISTERED.
CONNECTICUT HAS SOME OF THE
TOUGHEST GUN LAWS ON THE BOOKS
IN THIS NATION.
NOW THERE ARE CALLS FOR EVEN
STRENG
STRICTER GUN CONTROL.
AND DREW GRIFFIN HAS THAT PART
OF THE STORY AS WELL.
>> I CAN TELL YOU, WE KNOW THESE
GUNS WERE LEGALLY OWNED BECAUSE
OF CONNECTICUT'S VERY STRICT GUN
CONTROL LAWS.
LET ME TELL YOU WHAT THEY ARE,
ASHLEIGH.
THE TWO HANDGUNS IN THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT REQUIRE A
CERTIFICATE OF POSSESSION.
A FIVE-YEAR LICENSE TO OBTAIN
AND OWN THAT WEAPON.
IT COMES WITH THE REQUIREMENT
YOU GO THROUGH A TRAINING
COURSE.
A HANDGUN SAFETY COURSE.
AS FOR THAT ASSAULT RIFLE, IF
THAT IS INDEED AN OPERATING SEMI
ASSAULT RIFLE.
THAT GUN IS BANNED IN
CONNECTICUT, HOWEVER, IF THE GUN
WAS PURCHASED AND IN THE
POSSESSION OF THE MOTHER PRIOR
TO OCTOBER OF 1993.
THAT GUN WOULD HAVE BEEN GRAND
FATHERED IN TO HER POSSESSION.
BUT THAT WOULD HAVE TO BE
REGISTERED TO HER WITH THE STATE
AS WELL.
VERY STRICT GUN LAWS IN THE
STATE OF CONNECTICUT.
YES, THESE GUNS WERE ALL LEGALLY
OWNED.
>> AND, DREW, THE SHOOTER IN
THIS CASE, ADAM LANZA, HE HAD NO
CRIMINAL RECORD, NO ONE CAN FIND
ANYTHING THAT HE HAS DONE WRONG.
WOULD THAT HAVE FACTORED INTO
WHETHER HE WOULD HAVE GREATER
ACCESS TO CERTAIN GUNS IN THE
STATE?
>> BEING 20 YEARS OLD, NO WAY HE
COULD HAVE PURCHASED A HANDGUN
LEGALLY, CERTIFICATE OR NOT.
HE'S TOO YOUNG.
HE COULD NOT HAVE PURCHASED THAT
ASSAULT RIFLE BECAUSE IT'S
BANNED UNLESS YOU HAVE THE
GRANDFATHER CLAUSE.
LEGALLY SPEAKING, HE COULD NOT
HAVE OWNED THESE GUNS.
WE'LL TURN TO THE FACT THAT THEY
WERE IN THE MOTHER'S HOME.
OBVIOUSLY ACCESSIBLE AND HOW
WERE THEY STORED, DID THE MOM
KNOW HE HE WAS USING THE GUNS,
TRAINING THE GUNS?
WE'LL LOOK AT THOSE TYPES OF
ISSUES.
AS FOR CONNECTICUT GUN LAWS,
ASHLEIGH, TO SAY THAT THE KID
COULD HAVE GONE OUT AND BOUGHT
THESE GUNS?
THE ANSWER IS, LEGALLY, NO.
>> A GLOCK AND SIG SAUER FOUND
ON HIS PERSON IN THE SCHOOL
AFTER HE APPARENTLY KILLED
HIMSELF AND THEN A BUSHMAST
BUSHMASTER .223 FOUND IN THE
VEHICLE THAT HE HAD APPARENTLY
LEFT ERRATICALLY PARKED OUT IN
FRONT OF THE SCHOOL.
DREW GRIFFIN, THANK YOU FOR
LOOKING INTO THAT.
DREW GRIFFIN REPORTING LIVE.
THIS PARTICULAR SCHOOL, NOT A
LARGE SCHOOL, SOMEWHAT SPREAD
OUT.
SANDY HOOK HAS A SQUARE
FORMATION, AND THE SHOOTER TOOK
A CERTAIN PATH THROUGH THE
SCHOOL.
BUT AS THEY SAID, THE OFFICIALS
SAID, HE WASN'T RUNNING THROUGH
THE HALLS AND SHOOTING.
HE WAS VERY SPECIFIC ABOUT WHERE
HE TARGETED.
HAVE A LOOK AT HOW TOM FOREMAN
LAYS THIS OUT FOR US.
>> 9:30, A NORMAL START TO THE
DAY.
APPROXIMATELY 600 STUDENTS IN
CLASS, 50 FACULTY MEMBERS.
WE DON'T HAVE A COMPLETE READ ON
THE LAYOUT OF THE SCHOOL OR THE
TIMELINE, WE'LL TRY AND PIECE
TOGETHER ALL DAY LONG AS
INVESTIGATORS HAVE.
SOME IDEA.
DAY GETTING UNDERWAY, A MEETING
HAPPENING UP HERE INVOLVING THE
PRINCIPAL, VICE PRINCIPAL, A
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST AND SEVERAL
OTHER ADULTS IN THIS AREA, THEN
AROUND 9:40, BEST WE CAN TELL
FROM WITNESSES, JUST TEN MINUTES
LATER, THE GUNMAN ENTERS THE
BUILD.
HOW DID HE DO IT?
THE NEW SECURITY SYSTEM, NOT
SURE HOW HE GOT PAST THAT OR IF
IT WAS LOCKED UP AT THAT POINT.
POLICE LOOKED VERY HARD AT A CAR
PARKED IN THE FIRE LANE.
STILL THERE SURROUNDED BY TAPE
AS BEST I CAN TELL.
SUGGESTED WOULD BE THAT SOMEHOW
THE GUNMAN CAME RIGHT THROUGH
THE FRONT DOOR, INTO THE SCHOOL.
AND PEOPLE THROUGHOUT THIS
BUILDING REPORTED AND ONE FIRE.
9:41, THAT'S WHEN THE CALLS
STARTED COMING IN TO 911.
THE PRINCIPAL, THE VICE
PRINCIP
PRINCIPAL, AND THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST, ACCORDING TO
WITNESSES, WENT OUT TO THE HALL
AND TOWARD THE GUN IF FIRE TO
SEE WHAT WAS HAPPENING.
SHOUTING, MANY SHOUTINGS AND
SHOTS.
HE CAME BACK INTO THE MEETING
ROOM WOUNDED.
ALL OF THE SHOOTING HAPPENED IN
A RELATIVELY SHORT PERIOD OF
TIME AND THE GUNMAN DID NOT ROAM
AROUND, BUT GENERALLY STAYED IN
JUST TWO ROOMS AND A HALLWAY
RIGHT UP
IN HERE, THAT'S, IN FACT, WHERE
THEY ULTIMATELY FOUND HIM.
9:45, TEACHERS TRYING TO PROTECT
STUDENTS ALL THROUGHOUT THE
SCHOOL.
SOME AROUND THE GYM MASS YUM
WERE TOLD TO HIDE IN CLOSE ELTS.
OTHERS LED OUTSIDE TO FLEE.
NOT REALLY CLEAR IF THAT
HAPPENED WITH TEACHERS OR LATER
HELPED OUT BY LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS.
WE KNOW THERE WAS A REAL EFFORT
THROUGHOUT THE SCHOOL TO GET THE
KIDS TO SOME SORT OF SAFETY.
THIS PICTURE FROM THE NEWTOWN
BEE.
AND ALL OF THE TEACHERS TRY TO
DO SOMETHING ABOUT IT.
THEY DIDN'T KNOW WHAT WAS GOING
ON.
IT'S UNCLEAR, AT WHAT POINT IN
THIS PROCESS THE GUNMAN DIED.
THEY FOUND HIMSELF DEAD IN ONE
OF THE THE ROOMS THERE.
THE SUGGESTION?
PROBABLY HE KILLED HIMSELF.
MORE DETAILS AS WE GO ON.
WE KNOW THAT LAW ENFORCEMENT
AGENTS ARRIVED AT THE SCHOOL,
THEY SET UP A PERIMETER OF STATE
AND LOCAL POLICE.
THEY ENTERED IMMEDIATELY TO
SECURE ROOMS TO FIND STUDENTS
AND MAKE SURE IF A GUNMAN WAS
STILL ACTIVE, THEY GOT HIM UNDER
CONTROL.
THEN THEY QUICKLY STARTED
LEADING STUDENTS AWAY FROM THE
SCHOOL, TRYING TO GET THEM OUT
OF SAFETY.
A HORRENDOUS EVENT.
VERY DIFFICULT EVEN FOR THE
OFFICERS INVOLVED.
THEY HAD TO TELL MANY OF THE
CHILDREN, AVERT YOUR EYES, CLOSE
YOUR EYES.
THEY KNEW THEY WOULD LEAD THEM
RIGHT PAST MANY OF THE VICTIMS.
>> OH, TOM.
SUCH A DIFFICULT DETAIL TO
LISTEN TO, THAT THE CHILDREN HAD
TO AVERT THEIR EYES AS THEY
ESCAPED THE SCHOOL.
YOU KNOW, IT IS NOT OFTEN THAT
THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES SHEDS A TEAR IN PUBLIC,
AND TODAY IT HAPPENED.
YOU'LL SEE THE PRESIDENT'S
MOVING TRIBUTE TO THE VICTIMS,
AFTER THE BREAK.
>>> THIS EVENING MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT I KNOW EVERYONE
PARENT IN AMERICA WILL DO.
WHICH IS HUG OUR CHILDREN A
LITTLE TIGHTER AND TELL THEM
THAT WE LOVE THEM, AND WE'LL
REMIND EACH OTHER HOW DEEPLY WE
LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT THAT CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT.
AND THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT
NOW.
AND OUR DAYS TO COME, THAT
COMMUNITY NEEDS TO US BE AT OUR
BEST AS AMERICANS, AND I WILL DO
EVERYTHING IN MY POWER AS
PRESIDENT TO HELP.
ALLY BANK.
WHY THEY HAVE A
RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
TONIGHT OUR GUEST,
THOMAS SARGENT.
NOBEL LAUREATE
IN ECONOMICS,
AND ONE OF THE MOST CITED
ECONOMISTS IN THE WORLD.
PROFESSOR SARGENT,
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT CD RATES WILL
BE IN TWO YEARS?
NO.
IF HE CAN'T, NO ONE CAN.
THAT'S WHY ALLY HAS
A RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
ALLY BANK.
YOUR MONEY NEEDS AN ALLY.
>>> FOR MUCH OF THE DAY, SO MUCH
CONFUSION ABOUT WHO THE SHOOTER
WHO PERPETRATED THIS TERRIBLE
ACT HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WAS.
THERE WAS CONFUSION, BECAUSE HE
WAS USING I.D. THAT DIDN'T
BELONG TO HIM.
IT BELONGED TO HIS BROTHER.
A BROTHER WHO IS IN HOBOKEN,
CONNECTICUT.
AND THAT CONFUSION LED POLICE
RIGHT TO THAT BROTHER'S FRONT
DOOR.
HE'S BEEN ARRESTED NOW AS WELL.
AND JOHN BERMAN HAS DETAILS HOW
THAT PLAYED OUT.
>> ASHLEIGH, THIS STREET WHERE
I'M STANNING HAS BEEN THE SIGHT
OF A HUGE AMOUNT OF ACTIVITY
TODAY, AND A NIHIGH NUMBER OF
QUESTIONS.
BEHIND ME?
THE APARTMENT BROTHER WHERE THE
BROTHER OF THE SHOOTER LIVES.
RYAN LANZA.
LED TO A CAR IN HANDCUFFS.
TAKEN INTO CUSTODY FOR
QUESTIONING.
ALSO QUESTIONED ACCORDING TO
SOURCES TELLING CNN, TWO
ROOMMATES OF THE BROTHER WHO
LIVES HERE, BELIEVED TO HAVE NO
CONNECTION AT ALL TO THE
SUSPECT.
THIS BUILDING BEHIND ME, A
FIVE-STORY BUILDING WITH TWO-
AND THREE-BEDROOM APARTMENTS, ON
THE STREET, HOBOKEN POLICE,
JERSEY CITY POLICE, BOMB SQUAD
REPRESENTATIVES, ALTHOUGH THEY
DIDN'T GO INTO THE APARTMENT
BUILDING, AND THE FBI HAD A
PRESENCE HERE.
THE FBI DID REMOVE MATERIALS
FROM THIS APARTMENT, INCLUDING
SOME KIND OF COMPUTER.
THERE ARE QUESTIONS ABOUT WHY
THE BROTHER WAS TAKEN INTO
CUSTODY AT ALL, ESPECIALLY IN
HANDCUFFS.
ONE POLICE OFFICER ON THE SCENE
DID TELL ME, APPARENTLY SOME
KIND OF CONFUSION THAT THE
BROTHER'S I.D. MAY HAVE BEEN
FOUND ON THE SHOOTER'S BODY.
THAT WAS ONE POLICE OFFICER
TELLING ME THAT, WE'RE NOT
CURRENTLY CONFIRMING IF RYAN
LANZA IS STILL IN CUSTODY.
IS THE BROTHER OF THE SHOOTING
SUSPECT IN CUSTODY.
AND THE SON OF A WOMAN KILLED
TODAY.
ASHLEIGH.
>> JOHN BERMAN REPORTING FROM
HOBOKE
HOBOKEN, CONNECTICUT.
AND THE LANZA'S FATHER ALSO
QUESTION.
THEY AREN'T SUSPECTS, BUT THEY
HAVE BEEN EXTENSIVELY
QUESTIONED.
IT'S NOT OFTEN YOU SEE A
PRESIDENT IN TEARS, BUT IT
WASN'T BUT A FEW HOURS THIS NEWS
HIT THE PRESIDENT'S DESK PRETTY
QUICKLY.
HE TOOK TO THE AIR WAIVES TO
OFFER COMFORT AND SUPPORT TO THE
FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
HERE IS THE ADDRESS HE MADE
TODAY.
>> THIS AFTERNOON, I SPOKE WITH
DANE
DAN MALLOY AND FBI DIRECTOR
ROBERT MUELLER.
I MADE IT CLEAR HE WILL HAVE
EVERY RESOURCE HE NEEDS TO
INVESTIGATE THE HEINOUS CRIME,
CARE FOR THE VICTIMS, COUNCIL
THEIR FAMILIES.
WE HAVE ENDURED TOO MANY OF
THESE TRAGEDIES IN THE PAST FEW
YEARS.
EACH TIME I HEAR THE NEWS, I
REACT NOT AS A PRESIDENT, BUT AS
ANYBODY ELSE WOULD, AS A PARENT
AND THAT WAS ESPECIALLY TRUE
TODAY.
I KNOW THERE IS NOT A PARENT IN
AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS, MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES TO HELPING
OUR CHILDREN FULFILL THEIR
DREAMS.
SO OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN TODAY.
FOR THE PARENTS AND
GRANDPARENTS, SISTERS AND
BROTHERS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN, AND FOR THE FAMILIES
OF THE ADULTS WHO WERE LOST, OUR
HEARTS ARE BROKEN FOR THE
PARENTS OF THE SURVIVORS AS
WELL.
FOR AS BLESSED AS THEY ARE TO
HAVE THEIR CHILDREN HOME
TONIGHT, THEY KNOW THAT THEIR
CHILDREN'S INNOCENCE HAS BEEN
TORN AWAY FROM THEM TOO EARLY
AND THERE ARE NO WORDS THAT WILL
EASE THEIR PAIN.
AS A COUNTRY, WE HAVE BEEN
THROUGH THIS TOO MANY TIMES.
WHETHER IT'S AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN OR A SHOPPING
MALL IN OREGON, OR A TEMPLE IN
WISCONSIN, OR A MOVIE THREATER
IN AURORA, OR A STREET CORNER IN
CHICAGO, THESE NEIGHBORHOODS ARE
OUR NEIGHBORHOODS, AND THESE
CHILDREN ARE OUR CHILDREN.
AND WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO COME
TOGETHER AND TAKE MEANINGFUL
ACTION TO PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS REGARDLESS OF THE
POLITICS.
THIS EVENING, MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT
IN AMERICA WILL DO, HUG OUR
CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER.
AND WE'LL TELL THEM THAT WE LOVE
THEM.
AND WE'LL REMIND EACH OTHER HOW
DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT, AND THEY NEED ALL OF US
RIGHT NOW.
AND IN OUR DAYS TO COME, THAT
COMMUNITY NEEDS US TO BE AT OUR
BEST ASAMERICANS AND I WILL DO
EVERYTHING IN MY POWER AS
PRESIDENT TO HELP.
BECAUSE WHILE NOTHING CAN FILL
THE SPACE OF THE LOST CHILD OR
LOVED ONE, ALL OF US CAN EXTEND
A HAND TO THOSE IN NEED TO
REMIND THEM THAT WE ARE THERE
FOR THEM, THAT WE ARE PRAYING
FOR THEM, THAT THE LOVE THEY
FELT FOR THOSE THEY LOST
ENDURINGS NOT JUST IN THEIR
MEMORIES, BUT ALSO IN OURS.
MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORIES OF
THE VICTIMS.
AND IN THE WORDS OF SCRIPTURE,
HEAL THE BROKENHEARTED AND BIND
UP THEIR WOUNDS.
>> WE ARE INDEED A NATION IN
MOURNING TONIGHT AND IT IS KNOWN
ACROSS THE WORLD WHAT HAPPENED
IN AMERICA, IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THERE HAS BEEN REACTION FROM
WORLD LEADERS WHO HAVE WRITTEN,
WHO HAVE MADE STATEMENTS ABOUT
THIS TRAGEDY, AND THEN THERE IS
THE REACTION FROM PEOPLE, PEOPLE
FROM ALL CORNERS OF THE WORLD,
WHO NOW HAVE SOCIAL MEDIA TO LET
US KNOW, TO LET THEIR FRIENDS
KNOW, TO LET EVERYONE KNOW ABOUT
WHAT'S HAPPENED.
JOSH LEVIN WITH ALL OF THE
REACTION ON TWITTER.
>> PEOPLE ALL OVER THE WORLD ARE
EXPRESSING THEIR HORROR AND
SORROW ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED.
THIS IS PART OF THE STORY.
THE GLOBAL ACTION.
THIS AREA WHERE YOU SEE THAT IS
ON SOCIAL MEDIA ESPECIALLY.
SOME OF THE TWEETS GETTING A LOT
OF ATTENTION, ONE FROM MAYOR
MIKE BLOOMBERG IN NEW YORK.
MY DEEPEST SYMPATHIES WITH
FAMILIES ARE AFFECTED AND MY
DETERMINATION TO STOP THIS MAD
SCIENCE STRONGER THAN EVER.
LET'S JUMP ACROSS THE POND TO
DAVID CAMERON.
PRIME MINISTER OF BRITAIN.
MY THOUGHTS ARE WITH THOSE WHO
HAVE BEEN DEVASTATED BY THE
CONNECTICUT SHOOTINGS.
THE DEATH OF SO MANY CHILDREN IS
TRULY HEARTBREAKING.
NOW, THIS ONE IS VERY
INTERESTING.
DEEPAK CHOPRA SAYS HE'S
OBSERVING SILENCE ON TWITTER AND
FACEBOOK FOR A PERIOD IN
REMEMBRANCE OF THOSE THAT HAVE
BEEN KILLED.
IT'S AN INTERESTING IDEA.
WE'LL SEE IF IT CATCHES ON.
TALKING TO YOU ACROSS ALL
PLATFORMS.
THE REAL TRAGEDY, WE KEEP
LETTING THIS KIND OF THING
HAPPEN OVER AND OVER AND OVER
AGAIN.
ANOTHER ONE, HOLD YOUR CHILDREN
TIGHT AND THANK THE LORD FOR
THEM.
ABSOLUTELY.
I AM DOING THAT.
AND I KNOW MANY OF YOU ARE AS
WELL.
THE FACEBOOK PAGE FOR THE SCHOOL
IS GETTING A PRETTY GOOD AMOUNT
OF ATTENTION AS WELL.
PEOPLE POSTING MESSAGES THERE.
AND WE HAVE AN ASSIGNMENT AND
iREPORT TO EXPRESS CONDOLENCES,
THOUGHTS FOR THE VICTIMS AND THE
COMMUNITY.
>> JOSH, LIVE ON THE TWITTER
REACTION.
AS WE LEAVE YOU TONIGHT, THERE
IS A VERY LARGE PROJECT THAT
LIES AHEAD FOR THE
INVESTIGATORS, FOR THE POLICE,
FOR THE RESPONDERS HERE.
THIS WAS SUCH A MASSIVE CRIME
SCENE THAT THE PROCESSING OF IT
ALONE IS GOING TO TAKE AT LEAST