INTO A DUET.
♪
THE PRANK ON ASAN WAS AN ATTEMPT
BY HIS RECORD COMPANY TO CREATE
A VIRAL VIDEO, BUT HIS MOM CRIED
AND SO DID ASAN.
>> ONE TEAR.
♪
>> TO THEM, THE SURPRISE WAS
NOTHING LESS THAN STEVIE
WONDERFUL.
JEANNE MOOS --
>> THAT WAS AWESOME!
AHH!
I LOVE YOU.
>> Reporter: -- NEW YORK.
>> THE LOOK ON HIS FACE.
I'VE MET STEVIE WONDER --
>> OF COURSE YOU HAVE.
>> -- AND HE IS ABSOLUTELY
FABULOUS.
THE LOOK ON HIS FACE IS
PRICELESS.
>> THAT'S ALL THE TIME WE HAVE,
UNFORTUNATELY.
"ERIN BURNETT OUTFRONT" STARTS
RIGHT NOW.
>>> "OUTFRONT" NEXT, VIOLENCE IN
AFGHANISTAN.
TODAY, A HORRIBLE ACT OF
VIOLENCE.
AN AMERICAN SOLDIER WAS KILLED
HERE AFTER A SUICIDE ATTACK.
IT HAPPENED AT A BASE IN
KANDAHAR, JUST A COUPLE OF HOURS
AFTER I VISITED THE BASE WITH
THE U.S. DEFENSE SECRETARY, LEON
PANETTA, AND IT'S A SAD REMINDER
OF HOW SAFE THIS COUNTRY REMAINS
AFTER 11 YEARS OF WAR.
I'LL ASK THE DEFENSE SECRETARY
ABOUT WHAT'S NEXT HERE, AS
AMERICAN TROOPS PREPARE TO LEAVE
AFGHANISTAN AND ABOUT THE FIGHT
FOR AL QAEDA.
LET'S GO "OUTFRONT."
>>> GOOD EVENING.
I'M ERIN BURNETT LIVE IN KABUL,
AFGHANISTAN, TONIGHT FOR A
SPECIAL EDITION OF "OUTFRONT,"
AS WE FOCUS ON THE FUTURE OF
AFGHANISTAN.
I WANT TO WELCOME OUR VIEWERS IN
THE UNITED STATES TONIGHT, AS
WELL AS AROUND THE WORLD.
THANKS FOR JOINING US.
TONIGHT, VIOLENCE ROCKS
AFGHANISTAN.
A SOBERING REMINDER OF HOW
AMERICA'S LONGEST WAR IS STILL
NOT WON.
WE STILL DO NOT HAVE A SECURE
AFGHANISTAN.
TODAY, JUST HOURS AFTER I
WRAPPED UP AN INTERVIEW WITH THE
SECRETARY OF DEFENSE, LEON
PANETTA, IN KANDAHAR AT AN
AMERICAN BASE, THERE WAS A
BRAZEN ATTACK JUST OUTSIDE THAT
BASE.
A SUICIDE BOMBER STRUCK, THE
TALIBAN HAD TAKEN
RESPONSIBILITY, AN AMERICAN
SERVICE MEMBER HAS BEEN KILLED,
TWO AFGHAN CIVILIANS WERE
KILLED.
THREE AMERICANS AND 18 AFGHANS
WERE WOUNDED IN THIS ATTACK
TODAY.
NOW, A TALIBAN SPOKESMAN NOT
ONLY CLAIMED RESPONSIBILITY FOR
THE ATTACK, BUT PRAISED THE,
QUOTE/UNQUOTE BRAVE TALIBAN
FIGHTER WHO CARRIED IT OUT.
ALSO HERE IN KABUL TODAY,
SECRETARY PANETTA MET WITH
AFGHAN PRESIDENT HAMID KARZAI
AND INVITED HIM TO WASHINGTON TO
MEET WITH PRESIDENT OBAMA NEXT
MONTH.
NOW, THE KEY QUESTION FOR THESE
LEADERS IS WHERE DO THINGS NOW
STAND AND WHAT'S NEXT?
11 YEARS, 2 MONTHS, AND 6 DAYS.
>> WE WILL NOT WAIVER.
WE WILL NOT TIRE.
WE WILL NOT FALTER.
AND WE WILL NOT FAIL.
PEACE AND FREEDOM WILL PREVAIL.
>> Reporter: JUST ONE MONTH
AFTER 9/11, PRESIDENT GEORGE W.
BUSH LAUNCHED OPERATION ENDURING
FREEDOM, THE WAR AGAINST THE
TALIBAN AND AL QAEDA IN
AFGHANISTAN.
THE SACRIFICE HAS BEEN STEEP.
MORE THAN 2,000 AMERICANS DEAD
AND MORE THAN 18,000 WOUNDED.
$642 BILLION SPENT, AND UNTOLD
NUMBER OF AFGHAN CIVILIANS
KILLED, AT LEAST 12,000 IN THE
LAST FIVE YEARS.
WITH THAT SACRIFICE CAME SOME
PROGRESS.
THE TALIBAN WAS REMOVED FROM
POWER AND --
>> I CAN REPORT TO THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE AND TO THE WORLD THAT THE
UNITED STATES HAS CONDUCTED AN
OPERATION THAT KILLED OSAMA BIN
LADEN, THE LEADER OF AL QAEDA.
>> Reporter: BUT AS COMBAT
TROOPS PREPARED TO COME HOME IN
2014, THE TALIBAN IS RESURGING.
JUST THIS WEEK, A MEMBER OF THE
NAVY'S ELITE S.E.A.L. TEAM 6,
THE SAME SPECIAL OPS GROUP THAT
KILLED BIN LADEN, DIED DURING A
MISSION TO RESCUE AN AMERICAN
DOCTOR WHO HAD BEEN ABDUCTED BY
THE TALIBAN.
AND EARLIER THIS MONTH, NINE
TALIBAN SUICIDE BOMBERS ATTACKED
THE U.S. BASE IN JALALABAD.
AND AFGHAN TROOPS AREN'T READY
TO FIGHT THEM.
DESERTION RATES ARE HIGH, AND
THE UNITED NATIONS REPORTS
POLICEMEN ARE JOINING THE
TALIBAN.
EXTREMISTS IN THE AFGHAN
SECURITY FORCES HAVE KILLED 33
AMERICANS THIS YEAR.
AND AFGHAN CIVILIANS FEAR THE
FUTURE.
>> Translator: I DON'T 100%
BELIEVE THAT OUR NATIONAL ARMY
IS CAPABLE.
EVERY DAY, WE HEAR THAT OUR
SOLDIERS ARE KILLED IN THE
INSECURE PROVINCES.
>> Reporter: 11 YEARS, 6 MONTHS,
AND 2 DAYS.
WHEN WILL THIS MISSION BE
ACCOMPLISHED?
THE ISSUE OF READINESS ON THE
PART OF AFGHAN SECURITY FORCES,
TO TAKE OVER THE FIGHT AGAINST
AL QAEDA AND TERRORISTS IN THIS
COUNTRY IS THE CENTRAL ISSUE TO
DETERMINE IF AMERICA STAYS AND
HOW MANY AMERICAN TROOPS WILL
CONTINUE TO SERVE IN THIS
COUNTRY.
THERE WAS A NEW PENTAGON REPORT
OUT THIS WEEK.
IMPORTANT IT CAME FROM THE
PENTAGON.
THEY'RE TRYING TO TELL A STORY
OF IMPROVEMENT HERE, BUT THE
PENTAGON REPORT ITSELF SAID THAT
ONLY 1 IN 23 AFGHAN BRIGADES IS
ACTUALLY READY TO FULLY TAKE
OVER SECURITY IN THIS COUNTRY.
AND IN AN ARMY WHERE 85% OF THE
NEW RECRUITS ARE ILLITERATE, THE
CHALLENGES CAN BE OVERWHELMING.
I SPOKE EXCLUSIVELY TO THE
DEFENSE SECRETARY, LEON PANETTA
TODAY IN KANDAHAR, AND ASKED HIM
ABOUT THIS DAUNTING CHALLENGE.
>> OBVIOUSLY, THERE IS A
LITERACY PROBLEM, WITH REGARDS
TO THE FORCES AND, YOU KNOW, WE
CAN CONTINUE TO TRY TO PREPARE
THEM FOR THE ABILITY TO TAKE
OVER ALL OF THIS SECURITY
RESPONSIBILITY.
I GUESS, YOU KNOW, THE GOOD NEWS
IS THAT, AS A RESULT OF THE
TRAINING EFFORT, THEY ARE
DEALING WITH ILLITERACY AND
PROVIDING QUICK CLASSES AS THESE
INDIVIDUALS GO INTO THE ARMY, SO
THEY'RE MEETING THAT
RESPONSIBILITY.
THEY ARE DEVELOPING THE KIND OF
TRAINING AND CAPABILITY THAT
THEY NEED, BUT THIS IS AN AREA
WE'RE JUST GOING TO HAVE TO
FOCUS ON, INTENSELY.
BECAUSE OVER THE NEXT TWO YEARS,
AND PARTICULARLY IN 2013, WE
HAVE TO REACH A STAGE WHERE 100%
OF THE OPERATIONS ARE IN THE
HANDS OF THE AFGHAN ARMY.
THAT'S GOING TO TAKE A LOT MORE
WORK.
>> SO IS THAT WHY THERE'S BEEN A
BIT OF A DELAY?
I WAS JUST LOOKING AT SOME OF
THE HEADLINES.
YOU SAID WE'RE GOING TO HAVE A
TROOP COUNT DECISION IN A FEW
WEEKS.
AND THEN THE LAST HEADLINE I SAW
WAS A COUPLE OF WEEKS AGO AND
YOU SAID, I'M GOING TO HAVE A
TROOP COUNT IN A FEW WEEKS.
WHAT'S CAUSING THAT DELAY?
ARE YOU NOT SURE OF THE RIGHT
NUMBER?
IS THE PRESIDENT HOLDING IT UP?
WHERE IS THE DELAY?
>> NO, I THINK -- I THINK, FIRST
AND FOREMOST, THAT GENERAL
ALLEN, HAVING DEVELOPED THE
CAMPAIGN PLAN FOR AFGHANISTAN,
IS THE ONE WHO REALLY HAS TO
COME FORWARD WITH THE
RECOMMENDATIONS AS THE TO WHAT
THE ENDURING PRESENCE WILL LOOK
LIKE.
AND HE'S PREPARED SEVERAL
OPTIONS.
WE'VE REVIEWED THEM AND THEN
ULTIMATELY THEY HAVE TO BE
PRESENTED TO THE NATIONAL
SECURITY CONSUL, WHICH REVIEWS
THEM AND THEN PRESENT IT TO THE
PRESIDENT FOR A FINAL DECISION.
THAT JUST TAKES TIME, AND WE
WANT TO MAKE SURE, OBVIOUSLY,
THAT WE MAKE THE RIGHT DECISION
WITH REGARDS TO THE SIZE OF THAT
ENDURING PRESENCE.
>> THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO ARE VERY
WORRIED THAT THE U.S. WILL HAVE
TOO FEW PEOPLE TO ACTUALLY
PROVIDE THE SECURITY THAT'S
REQUIRED.
AND SOME HAVE SAID THAT NUMBER
IS 20,000, AND FEWER THAN THAT
IS NOT ENOUGH.
IS THAT FAIR?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, IT DEPENDS ON
THE MISSIONS THAT WE'VE GOT TO
BE ABLE TO WORK ON, IN THAT
ENDURING PRESENCE.
AND THE KEY MISSIONS ARE THE
FOLLOWING.
ONE IS COUNTERTERRORISM, WHICH
MEAN
MEANS WE'LL CONTINUE TO CONFRONT
AL QAEDA.
AND THOSE THAT, YOU KNOW, HAVE
ALWAYS CONTINUED TO PLAN ATTACKS
ON THE UNITED STATES, WE JUST
WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT THERE IS
NO AL QAEDA THREAT HERE IN
AFGHANISTAN.
SECONDLY, TO DO THE TRAINING AND
ASSISTANCE THAT IS NECESSARY FOR
THE AFGHAN ARMY, AND THEN
THIRDLY, TO PROVIDE SOME OF THE
ENABLING CAPABILITIES FOR THE
FORCES THAT ARE HERE.
THAT WILL DETERMINE THE NATURE
OF THE PRESENCE, BUT THE BOTTOM
LINE IS THAT IF WE'RE GOING TO
ACCOMPLISH OUR MISSION, OUR MAIN
RESPONSIBILITY FOR SECURING THIS
COUNTRY HAS TO REST AT AFGHAN
ARMY.
>> SO YOU'RE NOT YET SURE ON THE
NUMBER.
IT'S NOT LIKE YOU'RE JUST
WAITING TO ANNOUNCE IT.
YOU'RE NOT SURE ON THE NUMBER?
>> NO, WE'RE WORKING INTENTLY
RIGHT NOW TO TRY TO DETERMINE
WHAT THAT IS GOING TO BE.
>> AND THE ORIGINAL MISSION HERE
WAS, I'LL QUOTE THE PRESIDENT,
RIGHT, TO DEFEAT, DISRUPT, AND
DESTROY AL QAEDA.
>> RIGHT.
>> IS THAT MISSION ACCOMPLISHED?
>> THE MISSION OF DEFEATING AND
DETERRING AL QAEDA, I THINK, IS
WELL ON THE WAY TOWARDS, YOU
KNOW, ACHIEVING THE MISSION,
WITH REGARDS TO AFGHANISTAN AND
THE THREAT THAT WE FACE HERE.
WE CONTINUE TO FACE AL QAEDA,
OBVIOUSLY, ELSEWHERE, NOT ONLY
IN PAKISTAN, BUT IN YEMEN AND
SOMALIA AND ELSEWHERE.
BUT, YOU KNOW, WE HAVE HAD
REMARKABLE SUCCESS GOING AFTER
SPECIAL OPERATIONS AGAINST AL
QAEDA HERE AND WE'RE CONTINUING
TO DO THAT.
I THINK, YOU KNOW, THE MAIN
CHALLENGE HERE IS, OBVIOUSLY, TO
MAKE SURE THERE'S NO SAFE HAVEN
FOR AL QAEDA, IN WHICH TO
CONDUCT ATTACKS.
BUT THE KEY TO THAT IS IN
AFGHANISTAN, THAT CAN SECURE AND
GOVERN ITSELF.
THOSE TWO ARE INTERLOCKED IN
TERMS OF THE MISSION THAT WE
HAVE IN AFGHANISTAN.
>> BUT WHAT IF THEY CHOOSE THE
TALIBAN?
>> YOU KNOW, I'M VERY CONFIDENT
THAT THE AFGHAN PEOPLE WANT TO
BE SOVEREIGN, THEY WANT TO BE
INDEPENDENT, THEY WANT TO BE
FREE FROM THE TALIBAN, BUT THEY
WANT TO BE ABLE TO DETERMINE
THEIR FUTURE.
AND THAT'S OKAY.
THAT'S WHAT NEEDS TO BE DONE
HERE.
IS TO HAVE AN AFGHANISTAN THAT
CAN DETERMINE ITS FUTURE.
>> WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT DEFEATING
AL QAEDA, YOU KNOW, YOU THINK
ABOUT SOME OF THE STATISTICS
HERE.
OBVIOUSLY, THERE'S STILL AN
INSURGENCY.
93 POLICEMEN IN ONE DAY JOINED
THE TALIBAN.
DO YOU THINK AL QAEDA WILL EVER
BE DEFEATED, EVEN HERE?
>> I THINK YOU CAN REACH A POINT
WHERE YOU SO SIGNIFICANTLY
WEAKEN AL QAEDA THAT ALTHOUGH
THERE MAY STILL BE A FEW PEOPLE
AROUND, THEY WON'T BE ABLE TO
CONDUCT THE OPERATIONS THAT
THEY'VE CONDUCTED IN THE PAST,
AND THEY CERTAINLY WON'T BE ABLE
TO PLAN THE KIND OF ATTACKS THAT
AMERICAN HAD HAPPEN TO IT ON
9/11.
AND THAT'S OUR GOAL, IS TO MAKE
SURE THAT DOESN'T HAPPEN AGAIN.
>> AND WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT AL
QAEDA AND WHERE IT IS, MALI IS
WIDELY NOW SEEN AS A SAFE HAVEN
FOR AL QAEDA, AND IS LINKED TO,
INSPIRED BY, WHATEVER THE WORDS
MIGHT BE, DOES THE UNITED STATES
HAVE TO INTERVENE IN MALI?
>> WE'VE GOT TO GO AFTER AL
QAEDA, WHEREVER THE HELL THEY'RE
AT, AND MAKE SURE THEY FIND NO
PLACE TO HIDE.
BECAUSE LET'S NOT FORGET, THE
MAIN GOAL OF AL QAEDA IS TO
ATTACK THE UNITED STATES AND
WE'RE NOT GOING TO ALLOW THAT TO
HAPPEN AGAIN.
AND IF WE'RE NOT GOING TO ALLOW
IT TO HAPPEN, WE'VE GOT TO GO
AFTER THEM.
IN YEMEN, IN SOMALIA AND YES, IN
MALI IF NECESSARY.
>> AND FINAL QUESTION ON AL
QAEDA, HOW BIG OF A THREAT RIGHT
NOW, AS YOU ASSESS THREAT TO THE
HOMELAND, IS AL QAEDA?
>> I THINK WE HAVE SIGNIFICANTLY
WEAKENED THEIR ABILITY TO DO THE
KIND OF COMMAND AND CONTROL AND
PLANNING THAT WOULD BE NECESSARY
TO CONDUCT ANOTHER 9/11 ATTACK.
AT THE SAME TIME, THEY STILL
CONTINUE TO THREATEN OUR
COUNTRY.
AND THEY STILL REPRESENT, I
THINK, PROBABLY THE MOST
IMPORTANT THREAT WE STILL FACE
IN THE WORLD.
>> ALL RIGHT, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH, SECRETARY.
"OUTFRONT" NEXT, VIOLENCE IN
AFGHANISTAN.
AN AMERICAN SOLDIER TODAY LOST
HIS LIFE IN A SUICIDE ATTACK BY
THE TALIBAN.
IT HAPPENED AT A BASE IN
KANDAHAR, JUST A COUPLE OF HOURS
AFTER WE DID THAT INTERVIEW IN
KANDAHAR WITH THE DEFENSE
SECRETARY.
IT'S A SAD REMINDER OF JUST HOW
UNSAFE THIS COUNTRY IS, AFTER 11
YEARS OF WAR.
WE WILL BE BACK IN JUST A
MOMENT, TALKING, GETTING THE
OTHER SIDE OF THE STORY.
WHAT DO AFGHANS REALLY THINK
ABOUT THE SAFETY HERE.
THAT'S COMING UP AFTER THIS.
KES
TO RIDE HER BIKE.
SHE KNOWS THE POTENTIAL
FOR MAKING OR LOSING MONEY
CAN POP UP ANYTIME.
THAT'S WHY SHE TRADES WITH
THE LEADER IN MOBILE TRADING.
SO SHE'S ALWAYS READY
TO TAKE ACTION,
NO MATTER HOW WILY...
OR WEIRD...
OR WONDERFULLY
THE MARKET'S BEHAVING...
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
Aunt Sally's
singing again.
It's a tradition,
honey.
[ singing
Christmas carols ]
mmmm.
[ Female Announcer ]
Make new traditions
with Pillsbury Grands!
Cinnamon Rolls.
[ Male Announcer ] IF SOMEONE
ASKS WHAT IT FEELS LIKE
TO DRIVE A JEEP GRAND CHEROKEE,
TELL THEM
IT'S LIKE BEING NESTLED
IN AN EIGHT-WAY, ADJUSTABLE,
HEATED AND VENTILATED SEAT
SURROUNDED BY A 500-WATT
SOUND SYSTEM
WHILE FLOATING ON A SUSPENSION
MADE OF BILLOWY CLOUDS.
OR YOU COULD JUST HAND THEM
YOUR KEYS.
♪
THERE'S A HEALTH COMPANY THAT
CAN HELP YOU STAY THAT WAY.
WHAT'S HEALTHIER THAN THAT?
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Sharable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>>> DESPITE TODAY'S DARING
SUICIDE BOMB ATTACK ON THE
KANDAHAR AIRFIELD BASE JUST A
COUPLE OF HOURS AFTER WE WERE
THERE WITH THE DEFENSE
SECRETARY, THE MESSAGE FROM THE
UNITED STATES IS VERY CLEAR.
TERRORISTS WILL NOT WIN HERE IN
AFGHANISTAN.
BUT WHAT IS THE REALITY ON THE
GROUND?
"OUTFRONT" TONIGHT, TWO MEN WHO
MAKE IT THEIR BUSINESS TO KNOW.
MATTHEW ROSENBERG IS WITH "THE
NEW YORK TIMES."
HE HAS BEEN BASED IN AFGHANISTAN
FOR THE PAST FOUR YEARS AS A
FOREIGN CORRESPONDENT AND A
FORMER MEMBER OF THE AFGHAN
PARLIAMENT.
I WANT TO BRING BOTH OF YOU GUYS
IN HERE.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR WAKING UP
EARLY IN KABUL HERE FOR COMING
IN AND TALKING TO US.
MATT, I WANT TO ASK YOU ABOUT
THIS ATTACK.
IT HAPPENED A COUPLE OF HOURS
AFTER THE DEFENSE SECRETARY WAS
IN KANDAHAR.
THEY DON'T KNOW IF IT WAS
RELATED TO HIS VISIT OR NOT.
HE TOLD ME THEY FAILED HERE AT
THE AIR FORCE BASE, TWO HOURS
BEFORE, AND THEN THIS HAPPENED.
WHAT'S THE REALITY?
>> YEAH, THEY FAILED, THE BASE
IS IMMENSE, THERE ARE THOUSANDS
AND THOUSANDS OF SOLDIERS THERE,
BUT THAT ROAD HAS BEEN BOMBED
BEFORE.
THERE HAVE BEEN ATTACKS
THROUGHOUT KANDAHAR BEFORE, THE
ENVIRONMENTS AROUND THE CITY ARE
STILL UNSAFE, THAT WE HAVE A
REPORTER WHO WORKS FOR US IN
KANDAHAR CITY.
HE WON'T DRIVE TO AREAS OUTSIDE
THE CITY WHERE THE SURGE REALLY
PLAID OUT.
IT'S NOT SAFE ENOUGH FOR HIM,
NEVER MIND WESTERNERS.
WE CAN NEVER GO TO THOSE PLACES.
SO, OKAY, I GUESS IT'S BETTER
THAN IT WAS BEFORE -- BETTER
THAN IT WAS AT THE HEIGHT OF THE
SURGE, BUT IT'S NOT MUCH BETTER,
AND IT'S PROBABLY MORE VIOLENT
THAN IT WAS IN 2009 AND 2008
BEFORE THE SURGE.
SO IT DOES RAISE OUR QUESTION,
WHAT DID WE ACCOMPLISH?
>> AND THAT IS A REAL QUESTION.
>> YEAH.
>> WHAT'S YOUR ANSWER TO THAT.
AS SOMEONE WHO SPENDS A LOT OF
TIME HERE, WHAT DID WE
ACCOMPLISH?
>> THERE ARE AREAS THAT ARE MUCH
SAFER.
THEY REALLY ARE.
BUT THEY'RE NOT SAFE ENOUGH,
YET.
AND THAT'S THE THING.
WE'RE LEAVING NOW.
AND IS THIS DONE, IS IT READY TO
HAND OVER TO THE AFGHANS?
EVERY GENERAL SAYS, WELL, THE
QUESTION IS SUSTAINABILITY.
CAN WE SUSTAIN IT?
WE'RE GOING TO FIND OUT THIS
SUMMER AND NEXT SUMMER.
AND I DON'T THINK, IT'S A
VERY -- IT'S AN OPEN QUESTION.
>> AND DAOUD, YOU JUST HEARD THE
SECRETARY OF DEFENSE SAY, LOOK,
WE'VE HAD SUCCESS IN DISRUPTING
AL QAEDA.
HE'S NOT DECLARING VICTORY, HE'S
SAYING, WE'RE ON THE PATH.
HE'S CAREFUL TO SAY THAT.
IS THAT THE REALITY?
WHEN THE U.S. LEAVES?
HOW BIG IS THE RISK THAT THIS
PLACE AGAIN BECOMES A SANCTUARY
FOR TERRORISM, WHATEVER WORD YOU
WANT TO PUT ON IT?
>> I THINK, I DON'T BLAME
AMERICAN OFFICIALS TO PAINT A
ROSY PICTURE.
IT'S NOT AS ROSY AS THEY'VE
PAINTED AND IT'S NOT AS BAD AS
SOME PESSIMISTS THINK.
BUT I THINK THE MOST IMPORTANT
SOLUTION LIES IN THE
NON-MILITARY ASPECTS OF WHAT
WILL HAPPEN AFTER THE U.S.
LEAVES, WHICH IS THE AFGHAN
GOVERNMENT'S RESPONSIBILITY.
AND ALSO, THE TURNING POINT WILL
BE THE AFGHAN PRESIDENTIAL
ELECTIONS.
I THINK THE AFGHAN PEOPLE CAN
AND WILL HELP THE SECURITY
SITUATION, AS THEY WERE
CONFIDENT ENOUGH THAT THEY HAVE
A GOVERNMENT THAT THEY CAN
RELATE TO, THEY CAN BE CONFIDENT
OF, THE RULE OF LAW, THE
GOVERNMENT HAS TO BE PROVIDED.
ALL THOSE THINGS ARE A BIG
QUESTION.
IF WE DON'T HAVE THAT ELECTION
THE WAY IT SHOULD BE, BUT THEN,
SECURITY WILL BE DETERIORATING,
BECAUSE PUBLIC SUPPORT WILL NOT
BE THERE FOR THE GOVERNMENT TO
HELP RECEIVE SUPPORT FROM THE
THEM AFGHAN PEOPLE.
>> AND IT'S INTERESTING, A LOT
OF THE PEOPLE THAT WE SPOKE TO
IN THE PAST COUPLE OF DAYS,
MATT, SAID, WELL, WE JUST TAKE
IT FOR GRANTED THAT THERE'S
GOING TO BE A CIVIL WAR OR A
REAL RISK OF A CIVIL WAR WHEN
THE U.S. LEAVES.
AND WE WENT TO A BAZAAR, AND
ASKED SOME AFGHANS WHETHER THEY
THINK IT'S GOOD THAT THE UNITED
STATES IS LEAVING AND HERE'S
WHAT THEY SAID.
>> Translator: AMERICA SHOULD
LEAVE AFGHANISTAN IMMEDIATELY,
GO BACK TO AMERICA.
THE MUSLIMS THEMSELVES SHOULD
LEAD AFGHANISTAN AND BUILD IT
WITH THEIR OWN HANDS.
>> Translator: WHEN THEY LEAVE,
THE AFGHAN GOVERNMENT HAS THE
CAPACITY TO LEAD AND BRING PEACE
TO THE COUNTRY.
WE DON'T NEED THE AMERICANS.
>> IS THERE NO NEED FOR AMERICA
TO STAY?
I MEAN, I KNOW THERE'S
NATIONALISM, THERE'S PRIDE, BUT
WHAT'S THE TRUTH?
>> I MEAN, WE DO NEED TO STAY TO
HOLD THIS TOGETHER.
NOW, DOES OUR PRESENCE HERE
HELP?
IT'S A MUCH BIGGER QUESTION.
THERE'S A STRONG CASE TO BE MADE
THAT WE PROVIDE AN ACCELERANT,
WE PROVIDE A REASON FOR PEOPLE
TO FIGHT AGAINST IT.
I THINK THAT'S WHAT THESE GUYS
ARE SAYING TO A AGREE.
THEY'RE ALSO SAYING, LOOK, WE'VE
GOT TO STEP UP ON OUR OWN.
THAT'S WHAT WE WANT.
READINESS.
AND THEN THERE'S THE MONEY
PIECE, THAT POST-2014, BETWEEN
THE CIVILIAN AND MILITARY AID,
IT'S LIKE $8 BILLION A YEAR.
AFGHANISTAN'S TOTAL GOVERNMENT
REVENUE IS ABOUT $1.5 BILLION.
HOW MUCH LONGER CAN WE PAY AND
IS THERE AN EXPECTATION THAT
THEY WILL AT SOME POINT BE ABLE
TO PAY FOR THEMSELVES?
THAT'S NOT REALLY CLEAR.
>> HERE IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD OF
AFGHANISTAN, IN KABUL, THAT
WE'RE IN, WEALTHY PEOPLE LIVE
HERE, DRUG LORDS, WAR LORDS,
MINISTERS, ALL KINDS OF PEOPLE.
BUT THE STREETS ARE TERRIBLE.
AND THEY'RE TERRIBLE BECAUSE
THEY WANT TO KEEP THEM TERRIBLE
BECAUSE THEY DON'T WANT SUICIDE
BOMBERS TO COME.
IS THAT EVER GOING TO CHANGE?
>> THAT'S A POOR EXCUSE, I
THINK, FOR NOT PAYING ATTENTION
TO YOUR JOB RUNNING A CITY AND A
COUNTRY.
BUT I THINK THINGS WILL CHANGE
IN THIS COUNTRY GRADUALLY IN
SOME CASES.
THE BIGGEST PROBLEMS IN THE
AFGHAN GOVERNMENT AND THE AFGHAN
PEOPLE HAVE IS, THINGS
DETERIORATED FROM THE TOP DOWN.
AND WE HAVE TO FIX IT THAT WAY,
FROM THE TOP DOWN.
>> IS MAFIA A FAIR WORD TO USE?
>> MAFIA IS AN UNDERSTATEMENT,
BECAUSE THIS GOVERNMENT AND THE
ECONOMY AND EVEN THE SMALLEST
THINGS RUN IN CIRCLES OF GROUPS
OF PEOPLE WHO ARE MONOPOLIZING
THINGS.
FROM THE PRESIDENCY, ALL THE WAY
DOWN TO THE LOWEST THING THAT
PRODUCES SOME MAJOR INCOME FOR
PEOPLE.
THE WEALTH WAS NOT SPREAD,
MANAGEMENT OF THE COUNTRY AND
THE BIG CITIES IS REALLY
TERRIBLE.
AND PEOPLE FEEL THAT.
THAT'S WHY PEOPLE ARE NOT
HELPING THE TALIBAN.
THEY'RE STANDING ON THE
SIDELINES.
AND WE HAVE TO CHANGE THAT.
>> MATT, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>>> ALL RIGHT.
WHEN WE COME BACK, WE'RE GOING T
TO BE TALKING WITH THE FUTURE OF
AFGHANISTAN WITH THE DEPUTY
FOREIGN MINISTER.
WE'LL BE BACK IN JUST A MOMENT.
[ bells dinging ]
♪ HARK HOW THE BELLS,
SWEET SILVER BELLS ♪
♪ ALL SEEM TO SAY
THROW CARE AWAY ♪
♪ FROM EVERYWHERE,
FILLING THE AIR ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
CHEX PARTY MIX.
EASY 15-MINUTE
HOMEMADE RECIPES
YOU JUST POP IN A MICROWAVE.
LIKE CARAMEL CHOCOLATE
DRIZZLES.
HAPPIER HOLIDAYS.
CHEX PARTY MIX.
A Hybrid? Most are
just no fun to drive.
Now, here's one that will
make you feel alive.
Meet the five-passenger
Ford C-MAX Hybrid.
C-MAX says ha.
C-MAX says wheeee.
Which is what you get,
don't you see?
Cause C-MAX has lots more
horsepower than Prius v,
a hybrid that C-MAX
also bests in MPG.
Say hi to the all-new 47
combined MPG C-MAX Hybrid.
HOW THEY'LL LIVE TOMORROW.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
Music is a universal language.
But when I was in an accident...
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
Information on my phone.
Connection to doctors who
get where I'm from.
And tools to estimate what
my care may cost.
So I never missed a beat.
We're more than 78,000
people looking out for
more than 70
million Americans.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO A SPECIAL
EDITION OF "OUTFRONT."
WE ARE LIVE FROM KABUL,
AFGHANISTAN, TONIGHT.
AND THE ATTACK OUTSIDE A U.S.
MILITARY BASE IN KANDAHAR TODAY
WAS ONLY THE LATEST BLOW IN A
NATIONAL SECURITY SITUATION,
WHICH IS INCREDIBLY PRECARIOUS
IN THIS COUNTRY.
I SPOKE EARLIER WITH THE DEPUTY
FOREIGN MINISTER HERE IN
AFGHANISTAN AND I ASKED HIM IF
THIS ACT OF TERROR TODAY CAUGHT
HIM BY SURPRISE.
>> NO.
I'M NOT SURPRISED.
TERRORISM REMAINS A THREAT FOR
AFGHANISTAN.
THAT'S THE NUMBER ONE THREAT TO
AFGHANISTAN'S SECURITY AND ALSO
BY EXTENSION, TO THE SECURITY OF
THE REGION AND THE REST OF THE
WORLD.
AFGHANISTAN, UNFORTUNATELY,
CONTINUES TO BE ONE OF THE WORST
VICTIMS OF TERRORISM.
>> CAN YOU WORK WITH THE
TALIBAN?
I MEAN, I'M CURIOUS, YOU'VE MADE
ALL THIS PROGRESS IN CERTAIN
AREAS.
YOU'VE TRIED TO DO THINGS FOR
WOMEN'S RIGHTS AND YOU'VE TRIED
TO HAVE A MORE FREE AND OPEN
SOCIETY.
WILL THE TALIBAN BE A PART OF
THAT?
WILL THEY ACTUALLY BE A PLAYER?
>> WELL, THEY HAVE TO BE.
THAT'S ONE OF OUR RED LINES THAT
WE'RE ABSOLUTELY READY AND I
THINK THIS IS, IN THE INTEREST
OF PEACE IN AFGHANISTAN, AND
ABSOLUTELY DESIRABLE.
NONETHELESS, THERE HAVE TO BE
SOME RED LINES.
SOME OF THE ACHIEVEMENTS THAT
WE'VE HAD IN THE LAST TEN YEARS
CAN'T BE NEGOTIATED.
WE HAVE A CONSTITUTION THAT
GIVES RIGHTS TO MEN AND WOMEN IN
AFGHANISTAN.
WE HAVE ESTABLISHED A DEMOCRATIC
PERSON THAT'S VERY YOUNG, STILL,
A LONG WAY TO GO, BUT IT'S STILL
ONE OF OUR BIGGEST ACHIEVEMENTS.
>> AND I THINK ABOUT THE BOMB
THAT HAPPENED TODAY IN KANDAHAR.
I WAS THINKING ABOUT SOME
ARTICLE THAT I READ IN THE GULF,
I TRAVELED THERE THIS WEEK.
A PRUDENTIAL POLICE CHIEF WAS
KILLED AND THERE WAS ANOTHER
ATTACK, OBVIOUSLY, LAST WEEK.
THE TALIBAN IS PURPOSELY, AND
THEY SAY, SPECIFICALLY TARGETING
GOVERNMENT OFFICIALS.
DO YOU FEEL THAT RISK EVERY DAY?
>> AS AN AFGHAN, YES.
AFGHANISTAN IS ON THE THREAT.
AFGHANISTAN FACES TERRORISM, AS
A THREAT, ON A DAY-TO-DAY BASIS.
SO I THINK THERE IS NO
DIFFERENCE BETWEEN MYSELF AND
THE AFGHANS WHO GOT,
UNFORTUNATELY, GOT KILLED AND
INJURED IN KANDAHAR TODAY.
>> AHEAD, YOU'LL MEET SERGEANT
FIRST CLASS JOSH BURNT.
HIS STORY IS AMAZING.
HE IS STATIONED AT THE STATION
WHERE A SUICIDE BOMBER KILLED
THREE.
WE'LL PLAY HIM A SPECIAL MESSAGE
THIS HOLIDAY SEASON FROM HIS
WIFE AND TWO CHILDREN.
ALLY BANK.
WHY THEY HAVE A
RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
TONIGHT OUR GUEST,
THOMAS SARGENT.
NOBEL LAUREATE
IN ECONOMICS,
AND ONE OF THE MOST CITED
ECONOMISTS IN THE WORLD.
PROFESSOR SARGENT,
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT CD RATES WILL
BE IN TWO YEARS?
NO.
IF HE CAN'T, NO ONE CAN.
THAT'S WHY ALLY HAS
A RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
ALLY BANK.
YOUR MONEY NEEDS AN ALLY.
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAND.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
Every human being
is unique.
And there is one store
that recognizes it.
The Sleep Number Store.
The only place in the
world you'll find the
extraordinarily comfortable
Sleep Number Experience.
An exclusive collection of
innovations that totally
individualize your sleep.
Perfectly comfortable
pillows that adjust to
your size and shape.
Temperature-balancing
bedding.
Dual warmth comforters.
All designed around the
Sleep Number Bed: A bed
with dual-air technology
that allows you to adjust
to the support your
body needs.
Each of your bodies.
In the name of human
individuality: The Sleep
Number Collection.
Discover how our sleep
professionals can
individualize your sleep
experience.
Exclusively at one of our 400
Sleep Number Stores nationwide.
Sleep Number.
Comfort Individualized.
This holiday season, give
the gift that's magical:
the innovative AirFit
adjustable pillow at
special 30% savings.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO A SPECIAL
EDITION OF "OUTFRONT."
WE ARE LIVE IN KABUL,
AFGHANISTAN, TONIGHT.
I WANT TO WELCOME OUR VIEWERS IN
THE UNITED STATES AND AROUND THE
WORLD.
WE'LL HAVE MORE ON OUR REPORTING
FROM AFGHANISTAN IN JUST A
MOMENT, BUT FIRST, WE WANT TO
UPDATE YOU ON SOME OF THE BIG
STORIES MAKING NEWS IN THE
UNITED STATES TONIGHT.
>>> SUSAN RICE, THE UNITED
STATES AMBASSADOR TO THE UNITED
NATIONS WILL NOT BE THE NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE.
A SOMEWHAT SURPRISING MOVE IN A
LETTER TO THE PRESIDENT,
PRESIDENT OBAMA, SHE WITHDREW
HER NAME FROM CONSIDERATION
TODAY.
SHE SAYS SHE'S CONCERNED THAT
HER CRITICISM OF HER HANDLING OF
THE ATTACK IN BENGHAZI WOULD
LEAD TO A LENGTHY AND DISRUPTIVE
CONFIRMATION PROCESS.
THE PRESIDENT WILL MEET WITH
RICE TOMORROW AT THE WHITE
HOUSE.
>>> AND SPEAKING OF WHITE HOUSE
MEETINGS, PRESIDENT OBAMA AND
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER MET
AT THE WHITE HOUSE FOR ABOUT AN
HOUR TONIGHT.
AN IMPORTANT MEETING AND WE'RE
GLAD IT WAS AN HOUR.
MAYBE THEY CAN GET SOMETHING
DONE ON THE FISCAL CLIFF.
THE HOPE IS THAT THEY'LL HAVE A
MEETING OF THE MINDS ON THE TAX
HIKES AND THE AUTOMATIC SPENDING
CUTS THAT ARE SET TO STRIKE THE
UNITED STATES IN THE BEGINNING
OF JANUARY.
TIME IS RUNNING OUT.
THE FISCAL CLIFF IS 19 DAYS
AWAY.
AND OUR JESSICA YELLIN REPORTS
THAT SOME IN WASHINGTON BELIEVE
THAT A DEAL HAS TO BE DONE BY
TOMORROW IN ORDER TO GET IT
THROUGH CONGRESS BEFORE THE END
OF THE YEAR.
>>> AND BACK HERE IN KABUL,
AFGHANISTAN, WHERE WE ARE TAKING
A LOOK AT AMERICA'S 11-YEAR WAR,
THE LONGEST WAR HERE IN AMERICA,
WHERE DO THINGS STAND TODAY?
WHAT IS THE FUTURE FOR
AFGHANISTAN?
ONE OF THE MAIN CONCERNS HERE ON
THE GROUND IS SECURITY.
JUST A FEW HOURS, WE HAD A STARK
REMINDER OF THAT HERE, WHEN
THERE WAS A SUICIDE ATTACK RIGHT
AT THE ENTRANCE OF THE KANDAHAR
AIRFIELD.
THAT WAS A BASE THAT THE DEFENSE
SECRETARY, LEON PANETTA HAD
INTERVIEWED TWO YEARS BEFORE.
THE EXPLOSION KILLED ONE SERVICE
MEMBER AND TWO AFGHAN CIVILIANS.
THE TALIBAN CLAIMED
RESPONSIBILITY, CALLING THE
BOMBER A QUOTE/UNQUOTE BRAVE
FIGHTER.
PANETTA LATER SAID TERRORISTS
RESORT TO THESE TYPES OF ATTACKS
IN ORDER TO CREATE CHAOS.
WELL, CHAOS OR NOT, THERE ARE
68,000 AMERICAN TROOPS WHO ARE
RISKING THEIR LIVES RIGHT HERE
IN THIS COUNTRY TONIGHT.
MANY OF THEM ARE GOING TO BE
SEPARATED FROM THEIR FAMILY AND
FRIENDS FOR AS LONG AS 15
MONTHS, SERVING THEIR COUNTRY,
BEFORE THEY GO HOME.
IT'S A HARD AND STRESSFUL
SITUATION.
THERE IS SO MUCH SACRIFICE.
BUT AS WE LEARNED FROM THE BURNT
FAMILY, IT IS SOMETHING THAT
FAMILIES AT HOME LEARN TO DEAL
WITH.
McKENZIE BURNT KNOWS WHAT IT
MEANS THE TO MAKE SACRIFICES FOR
YOUR COUNTRY.
HER HUSBAND IS SERVING IN THE
SECOND STRIKER BRIGADE IN
AFGHANISTAN.
THIS WILL BE HIS THIRD CHRISTMAS
AT WAR.
>> MOST PEOPLE TAKE FOR GRANTED
THEIR HUSBANDS COMING HOME AT
5:00 AT NIGHT OR BEING HOME ON
THE WEEKENDS OR BEING THERE FOR
HOLIDAYS AND MILITARY FAMILIES
DON'T GET THAT.
WE DON'T HAVE THAT OPPORTUNITY.
>> Reporter: NOW IN HIS FOURTH
DEPLOYMENT, JOSH IS ON A MISSION
IN KANDAHAR AND HAS BEEN AWAY
FROM HIS WIFE AND TWO CHILDREN
FOR SEVEN MONTHS.
>> IT COMES WITH THAT, IT'S
MISSED BIRTHDAYS, ANNIVERSARIES,
FIRST STEPS, CRAWLING.
THEY MISS OUT ON SO MANY THINGS
IN LIFE, THAT ARE JUST
MILESTONES.
>> MARRIED AT AGE 20, McKENZIE
SAYS BEING SEPARATED FOR LONG
STRETCHES HAS BEEN ALL SHE'S
EVER KNOWN.
>> THAT'S MY BOOK.
>> Reporter: AND WHILE
5-YEAR-OLD JOSH JR. AND
9-YEAR-OLD HALLEY TALK TO THEIR
DAD ON THE PHONE ALMOST EVERY
DAY FROM THEIR HOME IN PUYALLUP,
WASHINGTON, HALLEY SAYS IT JUST
ISN'T THE SAME.
>> THE MOST THINGS I MISS ABOUT
MY DAD IS THAT HE'D ALWAYS MAKE
US LAUGH AND HE'D ALWAYS FIND
SOMETHING FUN FOR US TO DO IF WE
DIDN'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
>> Reporter: McKENZIE SAYS
LIVING HALFWAY AROUND THE WORLD
FROM YOUR SPOUSE CAN BE REALLY
HARD.
>> I HAVE CAUGHT MYSELF HAVING
MOMENTS, WHERE I SAY, GOD, I
REALLY WISH HE WAS HERE RIGHT
NOW.
I MEAN, THOSE ARE NATURAL TO
HAVE.
BUT YOU CAN'T DWELL ON IT.
IT'S NOT GOING TO CHANGE.
>> Reporter: THE BERENDTED HAVE
LEARNED TO BRIDGE THE GAP, USING
FACE TIME AND E-MAIL.
BUT MOSTLY, THEY TAKE A LOT OF
PICTURES, FOCUS ON THEIR
MEMORIES, AND ANXIOUSLY AWAIT
JOSH'S NEXT HOMECOMING.
>> EVERY DAY WE EAT ONE M&M, AND
THAT REPRESENTS ONE MORE DAY OF
HIM BEING CLOSER TO COMING HOME.
>> SERGEANT BERNDT TOLD ME ABOUT
THOSE M&Ms AND SAID IT IS A
SPECIAL MOMENT FOR HIM EVERY
MONTH.
HE IS SCHEDULED TO COME HOME IN
TWO MONTHS, HE WON'T BE HOME FOR
CHRISTMAS.
I HAD A CHANCE TO SPEAK WITH HIM
AT THE BASE IN KANDAHAR, WHERE
HE TOLD ME ABOUT HIS THOUGHTS ON
HIS JOB AND THE FUTURE FOR
AFGHANISTAN.
YOU GO OUT IN THIS EVERY DAY?
>> YES, MA'AM.
THIS IS AN M-WRAP.
IT'S A VEHICLE THAT WE USE, IT
CARRIES ROUGHLY FIVE PERSONNEL.
YOU HAVE THE DRIVER, THE TANK
COMMANDER, WHICH IS A PASSENGER,
AND THE TWO DISMOUNTS IN THE
BACK AND THE FIFTH PERSON WILL
BE, OF COURSE, THE GUNNER, WHO
IS UP TOP.
>> AND WHERE DO YOU SIT?
>> I SIT ON THE T-SEAT, THE TANK
COMMANDER, WHICH IS IN CONTROL,
BASICALLY, OF THE VEHICLE.
AND AS WE GO OUT, YOU KNOW, I'M
IN CHARGE OF CONTROLLING THIS
VEHICLE, WHERE WE'RE GOING, WHAT
THE GUNNER DOES, IF I NEED TO
REACT TO CERTAIN THING THINGS, M
BASICALLY THE PASSENGER, THE TC
OR SHOTGUN SEAT, IF YOU WANT TO
SAY.
>> SO DO YOU EVER -- I GUESS
I -- DO YOU EVER GET SCARED?
>> I GUESS IT'S ONLY HUMAN
NATURE TO GET SCARED, IN SOME
WAY, SHAPE, OR FORM.
BUT YOU DO IT SO MANY TIMES, YOU
GET USED TO IT IN, IN A WAY.
AND I'VE BEEN TRAINING WITH
THESE PEOPLE SO LONG, WE ALMOST
KNOW WHAT WE'RE GOING TO DO
BEFORE WE DO IT.
AND IT IS SECOND NATURE FOR US
AND IT'S PRETTY EASY AT TIMES.
>> AND YOU SAY IT'S SECOND
NATURE, AND YOU KNOW THESE
PEOPLE BETTER THAN ANYONE IN THE
WORLD.
IS THIS SORT OF LIKE A SECOND
FAMILY TO YOU, IN ANY WAY?
>> THIS IS DEFINITELY MY SECOND
FAMILY.
EVEN AS I CAME INTO THE
MILITARY, MY WIFE, IN GENERAL,
WE KNEW THAT THIS WAS A BIG PART
OF OUR FAMILY.
AND MY WIFE HAS ACCEPTED
EVERYONE THAT I'VE TRAINED OR
BEEN LEADERS OF AND IT IS
DEFINITELY A SECOND FAMILY FOR
ME, DEFINITELY.
>> AND THIS HAS BEEN YOUR CAREER
FROM THE BEGINNING?
>> THIS HAS BEEN MY CAREER FROM
THE BEGINNING.
I'VE BEEN IN 12 YEARS.
AND THIS IS DEFINITELY, WHATEVER
I DO, I EXCEL AT, AND I TRY TO
MAKE THE BEST OUT OF IT, AND
THIS IS DEFINITELY WHAT I'VE
DONE MY WHOLE CAREER.
>> YOU KNOW A LOT OF PEOPLE AT
HOME, THEY WONDER, DID AMERICA
REALLY GET ANYTHING OUT OF THIS
WAR?
WHAT HAVE WE ACCOMPLISHED?
AND YOU'RE HERE EVER DAY, YOU'RE
FIGHTING, YOU'RE PATROLLING HERE
IN KANDAHAR.
WHAT HAVE WE GOTTEN OUT OF THIS?
>> WE'VE GOTTEN QUITE A BIT.
I MEAN, HONESTLY, THE AFGHAN
PEOPLE, EVEN FROM WHAT I WAS
DEPLOYED IN IRAQ IN '03, DURING
THE INVASION, YOU COULD SEE THE
IRAQ PEOPLE AND THE AFGHAN
PEOPLE STARTING TO DO STUFF ON
THEIR OWN.
HAVING MORE FREEDOM AND STUFF
LIKE THAT.
AND THAT IS A BIG THING THAT I
TAKE OUT OF THIS.
IS THEM BEING ABLE TO DO STUFF
ON THEIR OWN, WITHOUT HAVING
SOMEONE, YOU KNOW, TELLING THEM
EXACTLY WHAT THEY HAVE TO DO
EVERY DAY OF THEIR LIVES.
AND I THINK THAT'S FREEDOM AND
STUFF LIKE THAT IS A BIG
ACCOMPLISHMENT FOR ME, BEING
HERE, THIS IS MY FOURTH TIME,
AND SEEING THE GAINS THAT WE
HAVE MADE THROUGHOUT THE YEARS.
>> AND DO YOU THINK, FROM WHERE
YOU SIT, THAT AFGHANISTAN IS
GOING TO BE READY, FOR PEOPLE
LIKE YOU TO GO HOME?
>> YES, I DEFINITELY DO.
I'M GOING ON PATROL WITH THE
PARTNERS.
>> YOU GO OUT WITH THEM, BECAUSE
YOU'RE TRAINING THEM --?
>> EXACTLY.
AND THEY DO THINGS ON THEIR OWN
THAT YEARS AGO THEY WERE NOT
DOING ON THEIR OWN.
THE LOGISTICS PART OF IT AND ALL
THAT STUFF.
THEY ARE SUSTAINABLE BY
THEMSELVES.
>> WE HEAR A LOT, THOUGH, ABOUT
AFGHANS WHO WORK WITH AMERICANS
AND THEN THEY WILL BLOW
THEMSELVES UP AND KILL
AMERICANS.
DO YOU HAVE A FEAR THAT THAT
COULD HAPPEN?
>> IT WOULD BE ALMOST UNHUMAN TO
THINK THAT IN THE BACK OF YOUR
MIND, YOU DON'T WANT TO GET WHAT
WE CALL COMPLACENT, BUT WE'VE
BUILT SUCH A TRUST WITH THESE
GUYS THAT THE IN AND OUT DAYS OF
WORKING WITH THEM, THAT STUFF
JUST GOES TO THE WAYSIDE,
BECAUSE YOU HAVE TO TREAT THEM
AS ONE OF YOUR BROTHERS, WORKING
WITH THEM, AND ONE OF YOUR OWN
SOLDIERS, ALSO.
>> AND YOU'RE ABLE TO DO THAT?
>> TOTALLY FINE, YES.
>> SERGEANT, WHAT MAKES YOU THE
MOST PROUD ABOUT WHAT YOU'VE
DONE HERE?
>> I THINK THE MOST PROUD IS
JUST SEEING THE KIDS, AND THAT
GENERATION THAT ARE GOING TO
HAVE A BRIGHT FUTURE HERE IN
AFGHANISTAN.
THE ELDERS AND STUFF ARE STILL
IN THAT MIND-SET, BUT THE
YOUNGER GENERATIONS, WHAT --
THEY HAVE SOMETHING TO LOOK
FORWARD TO AS THE YEARS PROGRESS
IN THIS COUNTRY, IN AFGHANISTAN,
IS THAT THE SUCCESSES THEY CAN
MAKE, THEY CAN GO OUT AND BE
SOMEONE, RATHER THAN BEING
SECLUDED IN A COUNTRY LIKE THIS,
THEY CAN MAKE LIVES FOR
THEMSELVES, OUTSIDE OF HERE.
>> AND WOULD YOU GO TO ANOTHER
WAR, IF THERE WAS ANOTHER WAR?
THE WAR ON TERROR CONTINUES.
GOES SOMEWHERE ELSE, WOULD YOU
STILL GO?
>> WITHOUT A DOUBT, YES.
THIS IS WHAT I SIGNED UP TO DO
FOR MY COUNTRY.
THERE ARE TWO REASONS WHY I
JOINED THE MILITARY, FOR MY
COUNTRY AND FOR MY FAMILY, TO
SUPPORT MY FAMILY, AND THOSE ARE
TWO THINGS I LOVE THE MOST, SO I
WOULD DEFINITELY.
>> THE TWO THINGS THAT HE LOVES
THE MOST.
AND WHEN HE TALKED ABOUT HIS
FAMILY, HE WAS EMOTIONAL.
THEY ACTUALLY HAD PREPARED A
SPECIAL MESSAGE FOR HIM, THAT WE
WERE ABLE TO PLAY FOR SERGEANT
BERNDT.
AND WE WANTED TO SHOW YOU WHAT
HAPPENED.
>> HI, HONEY.
WE LOVE YOU AND MISS YOU.
WE CAN'T WAIT TO SEE YOU.
WE HOPE THAT YOU HAVE A MERRY
CHRISTMAS AND THAT YOU COME HOME
SOON.
>> HI, DADDY.
I LOVE AND MISS YOU AND HAVE A
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
>> MERRY CHRISTMAS!
LOVE YOU.
BYE!
>> GOOD.
>> THEY MISS YOU.
>> I MISS THEM TOO.
>> AND YOU KNOW, YOUR WIFE WAS
REALLY STRONG.
>> YEAH.
>> SHE --
>> WHAT'S THE HARDEST PART ABOUT
NOT BEING WITH HER?
>> I MEAN, JUST BEING THERE
EVERY DAY, SEEING, YOU KNOW,
THEIR DAILY ROUTINE AND WHAT
THEY DO AND, YOU KNOW, JUST
GOING THROUGH, KIDS COMING HOME
FROM SCHOOL, DOING HOMEWORK, YOU
KNOW, MY SON PLAYING SPORTS AND
STUFF LIKE THAT, AND THINGS MY
DAUGHTER DOES, AND SHE'S JUST
SO, YOU KNOW, OUTGOING AND DOES
THINGS ON HER OWN NOW THAT I
DON'T SEE.
THE BIRTHDAYS, OF COURSE, AND
EVEN THE SMALL THINGS LIKE
MOTHER'S DAY AND FATHER'S DAY.
JUST THINGS BEING AWAY FROM THE
FAMILY.
BUT WE TRY TO DO THE BEST, YOU
KNOW.
BUT WHILE I'M DEPLOYED, YOU
KNOW, SHE KEEPS ME SO IN THE
LOOP AND WE TRY TO DO THINGS
TOGETHER STILL AS A FAMILY,
BEING THERE FOR THE KIDS,
SINGING HAPPY BIRTHDAY TO THEM
AND THAT STUFF WHILE THEY'RE
OPENING THEIR PRESENTS AND
STUFF, EVEN THOUGH I'M SO FAR
AWAY IN A DIFFERENT COUNTRY, WE
DEEP THAT BOND TOGETHER UNTIL I
COME HOME.
>> YOUR SON, I SAW SOMETHING HE
DID AT SCHOOL, WHERE HE WROTE
ABOUT HOW PROUD HE IS OF YOU,
BECAUSE YOU'RE DEPLOYED AND
YOU'RE SAVING PEOPLE'S LIVES.
>> YEAH, HE CAN BECOME A
STICKLER AND HARDHEADED, BUT I
THINK THAT DEEP DOWN INSIDE, HE
ENJOYS AND FEELS SO APPRECIATIVE
FOR WHAT I DO, AND ESPECIALLY MY
DAUGHTER, HALLEY, TOO.
THEY DEFINITELY KNOW WHAT I'M
DOING AND THEY KNOW THAT I'M
SAFE.
SO THAT'S ALL THAT MATTERS.
>> AND YOU SAID, THE ONE THING
SHE TOLD YOU IS THAT HE WAS
WEARING HIS PACKERS SHIRT.
>> YEAH, YEAH.
I DON'T KNOW IF I EMBEDDED IT IN
HIS HEAD WHEN HE WAS SUCH A
YOUNG KID, ABOUT BEING A PACKERS
FAN, BUT AS SOON AS HE KNEW HE
WAS GOING TO BE ON TV, HE HAD TO
WEAR HIS PACKERS JERSEY.
>> YOU WERE TELLING ME A STORY
ABOUT THE PACKERS WERE PLAYING,
BUT YOU WEREN'T HOME.
>> YEAH, EVERY SUNDAY OR SO,
I'LL CALL AND ASK HIM, AND I'LL
BE LIKE, JOSH, DO YOU KNOW WHO
THE PACKERS ARE PLAYING THIS
WEEK?
AND HE KNOWS TO A T WHO THEY'RE
PLAYING.
AND I'LL ASK HIM IF THEY'RE
GOING TO WIN OR IF THEY'RE GOING
TO LOSE.
AND HE ALWAYS VOTES AGAINST THE
PACKERS FOR SOME REASON.
AND I ASKED HIM, JOSH, WHY DO
YOU ALWAYS VOTE AGAINST THE
PACKERS, AND HE SAID, BECAUSE
YOU'RE NOT HERE, DAD.
AND I GET THAT.
A 5-YEAR-OLD SON --
>> HE MISSES YOU.
HE JUST WANTS YOU THERE.
>> DEFINITELY.
>>> NEXT, MY INTERVIEW FALLY
AKUFY.
THEY TRIED TO KILL HER AND HER
TWO LITTLE GIRLS, BUT SHE'S
STILL GOING TO RUN FOR PRESIDENT
OF AFGHANISTAN IN 2014.
HER VIEW OF WHERE THE COUNTRY IS
HEADED AND AN INSPIRATIONAL
MEETING WITH HER TWO DAUGHTERS.
SHE'S NEXT.
te"
Look who's back.
Again?
It's embarrassing
It's embarrassing!
We can see you Carl.
We can totally see you.
Come on you're better than
this...all that prowling around.
Yeah, you're the
king of the jungle.
Have you thought about going
vegan Carl?
HAHAHA!!
You know folks who save hundreds
of dollars by
switching to GEICO
sure are happy.
How happy are they Jimmy?
Happier than antelope with
night-vision goggles.
Nice!
Get happy. Get GEICO.
Fifteen minutes could save you
fifteen percent or more.
TRY RUNNING FOUR.NING
A RESTAURANT IS HARD,
FORTUNATELY WE'VE GOT INK.
IT GIVES US 5X THE REWARDS
ON OUR INTERNET, PHONE
CHARGES AND CABLE,
PLUS AT OFFICE SUPPLY STORES.
REWARDS WE PUT RIGHT
BACK INTO OUR BUSINESS.
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
WE'VE EVER WANTED TO DO
AND INK HELPS US DO IT.
MAKE YOUR MARK
WITH INK FROM CHASE.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
A REGULAR GUY
WITH AN IRREGULAR HEARTBEAT.
THE USUAL, BOB?
NOT TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
BOB HAS AFIB:
ATRIAL FIBRILLATION NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
A CONDITION THAT PUTS HIM
AT GREATER RISK FOR A STROKE.
[ GPS ] TURN LEFT.
I DON'T THINK SO.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR YEARS, BOB TOOK WARFARIN,
AND MADE A MONTHLY TRIP TO THE
CLINIC TO GET HIS BLOOD TESTED.
BUT NOT ANYMORE.
BOB'S DOCTOR RECOMMENDED
A DIFFERENT OPTION:
ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
XARELTO® IS THE FIRST AND ONLY
ONCE-A-DAY PRESCRIPTION
BLOOD THINNER
FOR PATIENTS WITH AFIB
NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
THAT DOESN'T REQUIRE
ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING.
LIKE WARFARIN,
XARELTO® IS PROVEN EFFECTIVE
TO REDUCE THE RISK
OF AN AFIB-RELATED STROKE.
THERE IS LIMITED DATA
ON HOW THESE DRUGS COMPARE
WHEN WARFARIN IS WELL MANAGED.
NO ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING
MEANS BOB CAN SPEND HIS
EXTRA TIME HOWEVER HE LIKES.
NEW ZEALAND!
XARELTO®
IS JUST ONE PILL A DAY,
TAKEN WITH THE EVENING MEAL.
AND WITH
NO DIETARY RESTRICTIONS,
BOB CAN EAT THE HEALTHY FOODS
HE LIKES.
DO NOT STOP TAKING
XARELTO® RIVAROXABAN
WITHOUT TALKING TO THE DOCTOR
WHO PRESCRIBES IT FOR YOU.
STOPPING MAY INCREASE YOUR RISK
OF HAVING A STROKE.
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU DEVELOP ANY SIGNS
OR SYMPTOMS OF BLEEDING,
LIKE UNUSUAL BRUISING
OR TINGLING.
YOU MAY HAVE A HIGHER RISK
OF BLEEDING
IF YOU TAKE XARELTO®
WITH ASPIRIN PRODUCTS,
NSAIDS OR BLOOD THINNERS.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE TAKING XARELTO®
IF YOU CURRENTLY HAVE
ABNORMAL BLEEDING.
XARELTO® CAN CAUSE BLEEDING,
WHICH CAN BE SERIOUS,
AND RARELY MAY LEAD TO DEATH.
YOU ARE LIKELY TO BRUISE
MORE EASILY ON XARELTO®,
AND IT MAY TAKE LONGER
FOR BLEEDING TO STOP.
TELL YOUR DOCTORS
YOU ARE TAKING XARELTO®
BEFORE ANY PLANNED MEDICAL
OR DENTAL PROCEDURES.
BEFORE STARTING XARELTO®,
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ANY CONDITIONS,
SUCH AS KIDNEY, LIVER
OR BLEEDING PROBLEMS.
READY TO CHANGE YOUR ROUTINE?
ASK YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
FOR MORE INFORMATION
INCLUDING COST SUPPORT OPTIONS,
CALL 1-888-XARELTO
OR VISIT GOXARELTO.COM.
>>> FAWZIA KOOFI IS THE FIRST
WOMAN ELECTED TO AFGHANISTAN'S
PARLIAMENT.
HER STORY IS AN AMAZING ONE AND
AN SPIRING ONE AND SHE IS NOW
CAMPAIGNING FOR THE PRESIDENCY
OF AFGHANISTAN.
SHE HAS LONG BEEN A TARGET OF
THE TALIBAN.
SHE WAS ONCE ATTACKED WITH HER
TWO DAUGHTERS.
SHE WAS SHOT AT IN A CAR AS THEY
DROVE THROUGH AFGHANISTAN.
IN FACT, SO OFTEN SHE RECEIVED
THREATS THAT SHE ACTUALLY NOW
WRITES LETTERS TO HER DAUGHTERS
EVERY TIME BEFORE SHE GOES AWAY
ON A BUSINESS TRIP, JUST IN CASE
SHE DOESN'T MAKE IT HOME.
I VISITED KOOFI IN HER HOME AND
I STARTED BY ASKING HER IF SHE
EVEN FELT SAFE THERE.
>> YOU NEVER KNOW WHERE YOU'RE
SAFE.
BECAUSE YOU MIGHT BE ATTACKED IN
YOUR HOME.
THIS IS SOMETHING THAT HAPPENED
TO THE POLITICIANS BEFORE.
THEY WERE EVEN ATTACKED IN THEIR
MEETING ROOMS AND THEY WERE
KILLED.
>> IN THE ROOM THAT WE'RE
SITTING RIGHT NOW IS WHERE, IS
PART OF THE WAY AFGHANISTAN
GOVERNS DIFFERENTLY, MAYBE THAN
THE UNITED STATES.
PEOPLE COME FROM YOUR PROVINCE,
THEY COME AND THEY ASK YOU FOR
THINGS.
AND EVEN LAST WEEK, YOU SAID YOU
HAD A SCARE, SOMEONE THAT WAS
COMING AND ASKING YOU FOR HELP,
BUT YOU THOUGHT THEY MIGHT BE
WEARING A SUICIDE VEST.
>> SOMETIMES PEOPLE COME WITH
VERY UNUSUAL AND EXCEPTIONAL
SITUATION AND THEY WANT TO PROVE
THAT THEY NEED REALLY OUR HELP.
SO FOR INSTANCE, LAST WEEK, THIS
MAN CAME WHO WAS A PATIENT, WHO
WAS A SICK PERSON.
HE NEEDED TO CHANGE HIS KIDNEYS
AND THE CURRENT KIDNEY DOESN'T
WORK, SO HE WANTED ME TO HELP
HIM TO GET TO THE MINISTER OF
HEALTH.
AND AS HE ENTERED, HE LOOKED SO
UNUSUAL THAT THE ROOM WAS FULL
OF PEOPLE, AND I HAD TO GO -- I
HAD TO RUN ALMOST TO THE OTHER
SIDE OF THE ROOM, THINKING THAT
HE'S FULL OF WIRE AND ALL OF
THOSE EXPLOSIVES.
BUT THEN I REALIZED THAT HE IS A
SICK PERSON, ASKING FOR MY HELP.
THAT'S AN INDICATION OF HOW
PEOPLE OF AFGHANISTAN HAVE
PROBLEMS AND HOW MUCH, BY DOING
SMALL THINGS FOR THEM, THEY
BECOME HAPPY AND THAT'S OUR JOB
TO DO SMALL THINGS.
>> AS A WOMAN, DO YOU THINK A
LOT OF THE, SOME OF THE
ACHIEVEMENTS THAT HAVE HAPPENED,
GIRLS GOING TO SCHOOL AND MORE
WOMEN WORKING, WOMEN LIKE YOU,
BEING ABLE TO BE IN PARLIAMENT
NOW, YOU'VE GOT MORE WOMEN IN
PARLIAME
PARLIAMENT, 27% OR 22, IT'S ONLY
18% IN THE U.S., SO IT'S BEEN
REAL PROGRESS.
DO YOU THINK A LOT OF THAT IS
GOING TO BE ROLLED BACK OR GO
AWAY WHEN THE U.S. LEAVES, OR DO
YOU THINK AFGHANISTAN WILL KEEP
THAT?
>> WE ARE WORRIED THAT PERHAPS
IN MANY PLACES, TALIBAN CLOSED
SCHOOLS FOR GIRLS, ESPECIALLY IN
THE SOUTH, AND RECENTLY, YOU ARE
AWARE OF THE SCHOOLGIRLS,
ESPECIALLY IN NORTH AND
NORTHEAST, BEING POISONED BY
TALIBAN.
SO WE KNOW THEIR INTENTION.
AND WE ARE WORRIED THAT ONCE THE
INTERNATIONAL COMMUNITY LEAVES,
ALL OF THOSE THINGS THAT HAVE
COME AFTER, AS AN ACHIEVEMENT OF
THE 2001, WOULD BE UNDERMINED BY
SECURITY AND BY THE SYMPATHY TO
BRING TALIBAN BACK TO POWERS.
>> AND ARE YOU GOING TO RUN FOR
PRESIDENT?
I KNOW PEOPLE SAY, LOOK, IT'S A
LONG SHOT.
YOU DON'T HAVE MUCH OF A CHANCE,
BUT ARE YOU GOING TO DO IT
ANYWAY AND GO OUT WITH THE
PUBLIC SPEECHES?
THERE'S OBVIOUSLY RISK TO THAT,
BUT IS IT SOMETHING THAT YOU'RE
DETERMINED TO DO?
>> I DON'T WANT BUY THIS
ARGUMENT, WHEN PEOPLE SAY, THERE
IS NO CHANCE.
IT'S JUST THE MIND-SET, IF A
WOMAN HAS A CHANCE IN OTHER
NEIGHBORING MUSLIM COUNTRIES OF
AFGHANISTAN, WHY NOT IN
AFGHANISTAN?
AFGHANISTAN HAS A LONG HISTORY
OF CIVILIZATION.
>> AS A MEMBER OF PARLIAMENT,
YOU'RE PART OF A GOVERNMENT THAT
IS RANKED 179 IN CORRUPTION IN
THE WORLD, OUT OF 180.
THAT'S A PRETTY TERRIBLE RATING.
AND I'M CURIOUS, BECAUSE, YOU
SIT HERE AS SOMEONE WHO'S TRYING
TO HELP YOUR PEOPLE, BUT DOES
THIS MEAN THAT EVEN YOU, WHO HAS
BEEN A HERO FOR WOMEN AND
INSPIRATION, A FIGHTER, THE
WORLD, THE OUTSIDE WORLD, WOULD
THEY DEFINE YOU AS CORRUPT,
EVERY MEMBER OF PARLIAMENT
CORRUPT, GIVEN THESE OVERALL
NUMBERS THAT WE SEE?
ARE WE MISSING SOMETHING?
>> I THINK, YES.
WELL, 20% OF THE FANS WHO ARE
COMING TO THE GOVERNMENT OF
AFGHANISTAN, 80% ARE BEING SPENT
THROUGH THE INTERNATIONAL
ORGANIZATIONS.
SO NOT ONLY IN THE BROADER
PICTURE AS THE GOVERNMENT OF
AFGHANISTAN, ALTHOUGH I AM NOT
IN POWER, IN A WAY THAT I AM NOT
IN POSITION, WE ARE THE CRITICS
OF THE GOVERNMENT, WE ARE
REFORMISTS, WE WOULD LIKE TO
BRING CHANGES.
I AGREE IN A WAY THAT THERE IS
CORRUPTION.
NOT ONLY MONEY CORRUPTION, BUT
ALSO POLITICAL CORRUPTION,
ADMINISTRATIVE CORRUPTION.
ALL OF THAT IS THERE.
>> FAWZIA HAS TWO YOUNG
DAUGHTERS.
THEY WERE BEAUTIFUL, SMART,
INSPIRING GIRLS AND I WAS CURE
ABOUT HOW SHE FELT ABOUT HOW SHT
THEM STAYING HERE IN
AFGHANISTAN.
IF THE TALIBAN COMES BACK.
>> SO, YOU WANT YOUR DAUGHTERS
TO STAY AFTER THE U.S. LEAVES TO
BE ABLE TO STAY IN AFGHANISTAN?
>> THEY BOTH WANT TO STAY HERE.
BUT IF THINGS GO TO THE -- GOD
FORBID IF THINGS GO REALLY BAD,
I THINK THEN WE WILL HAVE NO
OPTION.
>> WHAT DO YOU THINK?
WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN WHEN THE
U.S. LEAVES?
>> THIS IS OUR COUNTRY AND WE
CANNOT LET OUR COUNTRY GET DOWN.
WHATEVER HAPPEN, I NEED TO STAY
IN MY COUNTRY.
>> AND WHAT DO YOU WANT TO BE
WHEN YOU GROW UP?
>> A PRESIDENT.
>> YOU WANT TO BE THE PRESIDENT?
>> YEAH.
>> THE PRESIDENT OF AFGHANISTAN?
>> AND WHAT ABOUT YOU?
>> I WANT TO BE A SPACE
ENGINEER.
>> A SPACE ENGINEER?
>> YES.
>> SO PEOPLE WHO SAY GIRLS IN
AFGHANISTAN ARE GOING TO HAVE
BIG PROBLEMS, MAYBE THEY DON'T
KNOW ABOUT YOU?
>> YES, MAYBE.
>> AND WHAT ABOUT -- WHAT ARE
YOUR WORRIES ABOUT SCHOOL?
DO YOU THINK THAT IT'S GOING TO
BE THE SAME NEXT YEAR WHEN THE
U.S. LEAVES, THAT YOU WILL BE
ABLE TO STAY IN SCHOOL, OR ARE
YOU WORRIED THERE COULD BE
CHANGES THAT HAPPEN FAST?
>> I THINK THERE COULD BE
CHANGES, MAYBE TALIBAN COME
AGAIN AND MAYBE NOT.
I DON'T KNOW REALLY.
BUT I HOPE THEY DON'T COME.
>> I KNOW YOU WENT TODAY AND
HEARD YOUR MOM SPEAK.
>> YES.
>> WHAT DID YOU THINK?
>> I THINK SHE REALLY -- SHE WAS
GOOD AND I'M PROUD OF HER.
I'M PROUD OF BEING HER DAUGHTER.
AND THE SPEECH WAS REALLY NICE.
>> THANK YOU GUYS VERY MUCH.
>> YOU'RE WELCOME.
>> A SPACE ENGINEER AND
PRESIDENT.
THAT WAS AN INSPIRING MOMENT FOR
ME TO SEE THOSE GIRLS.
AS YOU OBVIOUSLY NOTICED, THEY
ARE VERY DEDICATED TO THEIR
EDUCATION.
WHEN WE WERE THERE, WE SAW THEM
UP IN THEIR ROOMS WORKING, THEY
WERE STUDYING.
I THINK IT'S FAIR TO MAKE SURE
THAT EVERYONE AT HOME
UNDERSTANDS WHAT THAT MEANS.
THEY WERE STUDYING, THEY WERE
DEDICATED IN, 30-DEGREE
FAHRENHEIT WEATHER WITH NO HEAT,
THEY WERE WORKING AND GETTING
READY FOR SCHOOL.
>>> WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A BREAK.
WHEN WE COME BACK, YOU'LL HEAR
OUR PERSONAL CONNECTION TO
AFGHANISTAN.
YEAH.
LET'S GO.
SAMSUNG GALAXY S3 --
OVER FIFTY DOLLARS LESS
THAN BEST BUY!
WOW! FIFTY BUCKS!
YEAH!
THAT'S A PAIR OF SHOES.
SEE FOR YOURSELF IF YOU COULD
SAVE ON THE GIFTS YOU WANT.
WALMART.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
IN THAT TIME
THERE'VE BEEN SOME GOOD DAYS.
AND SOME DIFFICULT ONES.
BUT, THROUGH IT ALL,
WE'VE PERSEVERED,
SUPPORTING SOME OF THE BIGGEST
IDEAS IN MODERN HISTORY.
SO WHY SHOULD OUR ANNIVERSARY
MATTER TO YOU?
BECAUSE FOR 200 YEARS,
WE'VE BEEN HELPING IDEAS MOVE
FROM AMBITION TO ACHIEVEMENT.
AND THE NEXT GREAT IDEA
COULD BE YOURS.
♪
AND THE NEXT GREAT IDEA
COULD BE YOURS.
Meet the 5-passenger
Ford C-MAX Hybrid.
When you're carrying
a lot of weight,
C-MAX has a nice little trait,
You see, C-MAX helps
you load your freight,
with its foot-activated
lift gate.
But that's not
all you'll see,
Cause C-MAX also
beats Prius v,
with better MPG.
Say hi to the all-new 47
combined MPG C-MAX Hybrid.
>>> FOR MOST AMERICANS,
AFGHANISTAN IS A COUNTRY THAT'S
SYNONYMOUS WITH THE WORD AL
QAEDA, THE WORD WAR, THE WORD
TERRORISM, WITH OSAMA BIN LADEN.
BUT THIS IS ALSO A COUNTRY WITH
AN INCREDIBLE HISTORY, AN
INCREDIBLE CULTURE, AND WE AT
OUTFRONT HAVE A SPECIAL
CONNECTION HERE.
ONE OF OUR COLLEAGUES, A P
PUBLICIST HERE AT CNN LIVED IN
KABUL IN THE 1970s AND I SPENT
SOME TIME WITH HER FATHER
TALKING ABOUT HIS LIFE HERE WHEN
AFGHANISTAN WAS A TOTALLY
DIFFERENT PLACE.
IN THE 1960s AND '70s,
AFGHANISTAN WAS A CULTURAL
HOTBED, ATTRACTING THE LIKES OF
JAZZ GREATS DUKE ELLINGTON AND
DAVE BRUBECK.
>> DAVE WAS IN KABUL, AND HE HAS
COMPOSED A BEAUTIFUL PIECE.
>> AS AN OFFICIAL IN THE
MINISTER OF CULTURE AND
INFORMATION, 77-YEAR-OLD FAIZ
EXPERIENCED KABUL IN ITS HEYDAY
WITH HIS WIFE AND TWO CHILDREN.
>> OUR HOUSE WAS A PLACE WHERE
ALL THE ARTISTS, INTELLECTUALS
FROM ALL OVER THE WORLD, WOULD
BE WELCOMED AND AFGHAN
COUNTERPARTS WOULD BE INVITED TO
EXCHANGE IDEAS, TO LAUGH.
>> YOU HAD THE SALON OF KABUL.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> BUT IN 1978, FAIZ AND HIS
FAMILY FLED THE COUNTRY AFTER
REVOLUTION AND THE SOVIET
INVASION.
>> IT SADDENS ME THAT ON THE
SPOT THAT I HAD BUILT A STAGE
FOR DUKE ELLINGTON TO PERFORM IS
THAT AWFUL FOOTAGE PLAYED ALL
OVER THE WORLD OF A WOMAN BEING
EXECUTED.
>> THE SOCCER STADIUM ONCE
HOSTED PRESIDENTS AND
DIGNITARIES BUT BECAME AN ARENA
FOR PUBLIC EXECUTIONS.
MORE RECENTLY SOCCER HAS
RETURNED BUT AFTER MORE THAN 30
YEARS OF WAR AND OPPRESSION,
FAIZ SAYS KABUL IS NOT WHAT IT
ONCE WAS.
FOUR YEARS HE WENT BACK AND
FOUND HIS ONCE PALATIAL
RESIDENCE BOMBED OUT, STRIPPED.
>> WHEN YOU FIRST WENT BACK AND
SAW WHAT HAPPENED, WHAT WAS THAT
MOMENT LIKE?
>> IT WAS A VERY, VERY SAD
MOMENT.
>> HIS HOUSE HAS SINCE BEEN TORN
DOWN AND TURNED INTO A WEDDING
HALL.
THROUGHOUT THE CITY, COUNTLESS
HOMES AND HISTORICAL MONIME YOU
MEA --
MONUMENTS HAVE BEEN DESTROYED.
THERE'S A SMALL SIGN OF HOPE FOR
THE FUTURE OF AFGHANISTAN.
>> I'M HOPING THAT SOME DAY
MAYBE MY CHILDREN, THEIR
CHILDREN WOULD BE LIKE ALL THE
OTHER MINORITIES WHO HAVE COME
TO AMERICA, LIKE ITALIANS OR
GREEKS OR IRISH OR ANYBODY, THAT
THEY'LL GO TO THE OLD COUNTRY
JUST TO SEE THEIR ROOTS.
SOME DAY I HOPE THAT WILL
HAPPEN.
>> TOMORROW NIGHT ON "OUTFRONT"
MORE OF MY EXCLUSIVE INTERVIEW
WITH THE DEFENSE SECRETARY, LEON
PANETTA.
WE TALKED ABOUT IRAN.
HE HAD SOME SURPRISING COMMENTS
ON IRAN'S PURSUIT OF A NUCLEAR
WEAPON AND HE ALSO TALKED ABOUT
THE GENERAL PETRAEUS AFFAIR.
>> THERE'S NO QUESTION IN MY
MIND THAT THE OVERWHELMING
MAJORITY OF OUR MEN AND WOMEN IN
UNIFORM ABIDE BY THE HIGHEST
STANDARDS.
BUT THERE ARE ALWAYS THOSE THAT,
YOU