THERE IS NO OFFICIAL SERVICE
HAPPENING.
THEY DON'T INTEND TO HAVE ONE
THROUGH TONIGHT.
BUT THEY SAY THEY' HAD MANY
PEOPLE COME THROUGH AND THEY ARE
TRYING TO BE ONE OF THE MANY
PLACES WHERE PEOPLE IN THE
COMMUNITY CAN GO AND HEAL.
POLICE ARE TALKING TO EVERYONE
WHO KNEW THE SHOOTER.
ALSO POLICE SAY THEY'RE GOING TO
TALK TO THE ONE ADULT WHO WAS
INJURED IN THE SHOOTING IN THE
SDOOL.
THEY USE THE WORDS INSTRUMENTAL
TO DESCRIBE WHAT SHE MIGHT BE
ABLE TO PROVIDE.
THEY'RE PIECING TOGETHER NOW
WHAT HAPPENED.
>> POLICE BELIEVE THE SHOOTER
CAME HERE AFTER THE MOTHER'S
MURDER, CARRYING WEAPONS LIKE
THESE.
WHAT HAPPENED THEN?
LET'S LOOK AT THE TIME LINE
BASED ON POLICE REPORTS AND
EYEWITNESSS.
9:30 IN THE MORNING, THAT'S WHEN
WE BELIEVE HE EMERGED FROM HIS
CAR AND HEADED INTO THE SCHOOL
HERE.
WE DON'T KNOW THAT THERE IS HIS
CHARACTER BUT THEY'VE PAID AN
AWFUL LOT OF ATTENTION TO THIS
VEHICLE OVER THE PAST FEW DAYS.
HERE'S ALSO WHERE HE ENCOUNTERED
HIS FIRST PABARRICADE BECAUSE
THERE WAS A SECURITY SYSTEM ON
THE DOOR.
PUT IN BY THE PRINCIPAL.
POLICE LATER FOUND THAT THE
GLASS HERE HAD BEEN SHOT OUT OR
BROKEN OUT BY SOME FASHION.
THAT SEEMS TO BE HOW HE ENTERED
THE SCHOOL.
SO WHAT HAPPENED AFTER THAT.
WELL, THE FIRST CALL TO THE
POLICE THAT SAID THERE WAS A
PROBLEM CAME AT 9:36.
THE FIRST CALL SAYING THAT THERE
WAS GUN FIRE INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
OBVIOUSLY PEOPLE IN THE SCHOOL
KNEW IT BECAUSE THEY COULD
EITHER HEAR IT DIRECTLY OR
BECAUSE THEY HEARD IT OVER THE
SCHOOL'S P.A. SYSTEM.
ALL THE SHOOTING TOOK PLACE
IN .A VERY SMALL AREA, UP IN
THIS PART OF THE SCHOOL.
SO IT WAS IMPORTANT THAT
EVERYBODY ELSE HAVE SOME IDEA
THAT THIS WAS GOING ON, SO THAT
THEY COULD TRY TO BE SAFE IN
THESE CIRCUMSTANCES.
BEYOND THAT, WHAT HAPPENED?
AT 9:38, POLICE WERE SAYING
ALREADY THEY WERE HEARING
REPORTS THAT THE SHOOTING WAS
OVER.
AN INCREDIBLY SHORT PERIOD OF
TIME.
2, 2 1/2 MINUTES MAYBE WHERE THE
MULLING,
BULK IF NOT ALL OF THE SHOOTING
TOOK PLACE.
THE NEXT PHASE, 9:40, POLICE AT
THE SCHOOL SAID WE NEED SOME
EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES HERE.
THAT'S THE FIRST CALL FOR
AMBULANCES.
IT'S FOR TWO AMBULANCES TO BEGIN
WITH.
AND THEN AS THEY REALIZED THEY
HAD MANY MORE VICTIMS IN A
MATTER OF MINUTES, THERE WAS A
CALL FOR MANY, MANY MORE
EMERGENCY MEDICAL TECHNICIANS
AND AMBULANCES TO COME TO THE
SCHOOL.
AND THEN SURPRISINGLY, BY 9:50
IN THE MORNING, WE JUST PUT THIS
BECAUSE THE TIMES HAVE BEEN A
LITTLE BIT LOOSE, BY 9:50,
POLICE WERE ESSENTIALLY SAYING
THAT THEY HAD A SUSPECT WHO WAS
DOWN, MEANING ONE SUSPECT WHO
WAS DEAD.
THEY HAD SECURED THE BUILDING TO
SOME DEGREE.
THEY CLEARED THE BUILDING IS THE
LANGUAGE THEY USED AND A LOT OF
THE KIDS WERE BEING LED AWAY.
THIS IS THE PICTURE FROM THE
"NEWTON BEE" OF THE KIDS BEING
LED AWAY.
IN ANY EVENT, THIS IS A SHORT
PERIOD OF TIME, 17 TO 20 MINUTES
THAT THIS WENT FROM NOTHING
HAPPENING TO ALL OF THESE EVENTS
HAPPENING THAT HAVE CHANGED THE
LIVES SO MANY PEOPLE.
AND POLICE WILL CONTINUE GOING
OVER AND OVER AND OVER AGAIN,
THE DETAILS OF THE MOVEMENT OF
THIS SHOOTER AND HIS VICTIMS TO
TRY TO GET A BETTER
UNDERSTANDING OF PRECISELY HOW
IT ALL HAPPENED.
OF.
>> TOM FOREMAN WITH A LOOK AT
THE TIME LINE FOR US TONIGHT.
LET'S GO RIGHT BACK TO DON
LEMON.
DON?
>> ALL RIGHT, SOLEDAD.
THAT'S WHAT HAPPENED INSIDE THE
SCHOOL.
WE HAVE SOME NEW DEVELOPMENTS TO
TELL YOU ABOUT FROM HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
THE PRESIDENT, PRESIDENT BARACK
OBAMA WILL BE HERE TOMORROW.
THE WHITE HOUSE SAYS THE
PRESIDENT WILL MEET WITH THE
FAMILY OF THE VICTIMS, THE 20
CHILDREN AND THE SIX ADULTS
KILLED IN THEIR ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL YESTERDAY.
ALSO, WE HAVE REACTION THIS
EVENING FROM PETER LANZA, THE
FATHER OF THE 20-YEAR-OLD POLICE
SAY KILLED THOSE PEOPLE AND THEN
KILLED HIMSELF.
THE FATHER SAYS, QUOTE, OUR
FAMILY IS GROOEING ALONG WITH
ALL THOSE WHO HAVE BEEN AFFECTED
BY THIS ENORMOUS TRAGEDY.
NO WORDS CAN TRULY EXPRESS HOW
HEART BROKEN WE ARE.
NOW, LET ME SHOW YOU THIS
PICTURE THAT WAS JUST OBTAINED
BY CNN.
IT SHOWS ADAM LANZA, BACK IN
2005.
HE WOULD BE ABOUT 13 YEARS OLD
IN THIS PICTURE.
AND WE HAVE WORD TONIGHT FROM
POLICE WHO ARE TRYING TO LEARN
WHY THIS YOUNG MAN WOULD COMMIT
SUCH AN HORRIFIC ACT.
THEY SAY THEY HAVE FOUND VERY
GOOD EVIDENCE IN ADAM LANZA'S
HOME THAT IS HELPING THEM PUT
TOGETHER THE PUZZLE PIECES IN
THAT INVESTIGATION.
THAT HOME IS ALSO A CRIME SCENE
NOW.
INVESTIGATORS SAY LANZA'S MOTHER
WAS KILLED IN THAT HOUSE BEFORE
THE DEADLY RAMPAGE AT THE
SCHOOL.
SOLEDAD, SO MANY MORE DETAILS TO
EMERGE ABOUT THIS STORY.
AND THIS IS JUST THE BEGINNING
OF IT.
>> NO QUESTION ABOUT THAT, DON.
WE WANT TO TALK A LITTLE BIT
MORE ABOUT ONE OF THE MORE
REMARKABLE TESTIMONIALS THAT WE
HEARD TODAY.
IT CAME FROM A MAN NAMED ROBBIE
PARKER.
AND HE WAS SPEAKING ABOUT HIS
DAUGHTER EMILIE.
AND WHILE HE WAS EMOTIONAL AND
JUST ABSOLUTELY DEVASTATED, THE
COMPASSION THAT HE WAS ABLE TO
SHOW WAS STUNNING.
KIM LA WAS THERE WHILE HE WAS
TALKING TO REPORTERS AND HAS
MORE FOR US.
KYUNG, TELL US MORE.
>> ONE OF THE THINGS HE WANTED
TO SAY WAS THANK YOU.
ONE OF THE REASONS HE CALLED
REPORTERS TO THIS CHURCH HERE, A
CHURCH HEIFER ONLY BELONGED TO
FOR ATE MONTHS BECAUSE HE MOVED
HERE TO TAKE A JOB AT THE
HOSPITAL TO TAKE CARE OF NEWBORN
CHILDREN.
TAKING CARE OF CHILDREN THEN
HAVING TO LOSE HIS CHILD.
HE CALLED REPORTERS HERE.
HEN'T WANTED TO SAY THANK YOU
BECAUSE SO MANY PEOPLE HAD
REACHED OUT TO HIS FAMILY TO SAY
WE ARE SO SORRY, WE ARE SO
HORRIFIE
HORRIFIED.
YOU KNOW, YOU CAN IMAGINE HOW
THIS MAN FEELS.
HE LOST HIS CHILD, BUT HE WANTED
TO TAKE THAT MOMENT AND THEN
EXPRESS THAT HE WANTED TO MAKE
SURE THAT PEOPLE UNDERSTOOD THAT
SOCIETY SHOULD NOT BE DEFINED BY
THIS MOMENT.
HERE'S A LITTLE BIT OF WHAT HAVE
HE SAID.
>> I WAS LEAVING TO WORK AND SHE
WOKE UP BEFORE I LEFT AND, I'VE
ACTUALLY BEEN TEACHING HER
PORTUGUESE.
AND SO OUR LAST CONVERSATION WAS
IN PORTUGUESE.
SHE TOLD ME GOOD MORNING AND
ASKED HOW I WAS DOING.
I SAID THAT I WAS DOING WELL.
SHE SAID THAT SHE LOVED ME.
AND I GAVE HER A KISS AND I WAS
OUT THE DOOR.
AS THE DEEP PAIN BEGINS TO
SETTLE INTO OUR HEARTS WE FIND
COMFORT REFLECTING ON THE
INCREDIBLE PERSON THAT EMILIE
WAS AND HOW MANY LIVES SHE WAS
ABLE TO TOUCH IN HER SHORT TIME
HERE ON EARTH.
EMILIE WAS BRIGHT, CREATIVE AND
VERY LOVING.
MY DAUGHTER EMILIE WOULD BE ONE
OF THE FIRST ONES TO BE STANDING
AND GIVING HER LOVE AND SUPPORT
TO ALL THOSE VICTIMS, BECAUSE
THAT CEASE THE TYPE OF PERSON
SHA TH
THAT SHE IS.
NOT BECAUSE OF ANY PARENTING
THAT MY WIFE AND I COULD HAVE
DONE, BUT BECAUSE THOSE ARE THE
GIFTS THAT WERE GIVEN TO HER BY
HER HEAVENLY FATHER.
>> Reporter: AND WHAT HE WANTED
TO SHARE IS THAT HE WANTED TO BE
LIKE HIS DAUGHTER, THAT HE WAS
NOT ANGRY, THAT HE WANTED TO
HELP OTHER PEOPLE.
HE SAYS HE NOW BELONGS TO THIS
GROUP OF PARENTS, 20 SETS OF
PARENTS WHO NOW KNOW EXACTLY HOW
IT FEELS TO LOSE YOUR CHILD IN
SUCH A HORRIBLE WAY.
BUT HE ALSO WANTED TO MAKE SURE
THAT PARENTS AROUND THE COUNTRY
AND AROUND THE WORLD UNDERSTOOD
THAT YOU CAN NOT TAKE YOUR
CHILDREN FOR GRANTED, AND YOU
REALLY, TRULY HAVE TO CHERISH
THEM WHENEVER YOU CAN.
SOLEDAD?
>> KYUNG LAH, REPORTING THAT
STORY FOR US.
THANK YOU.
IT WAS INTERESTING TO HEAR HIM
TALK ABOUT HIS FAMILY'S FAITH
AND THE DEGREE TO WHICH THAT WAS
HELPING HIS FAMILY COPE AT THIS
TIME.
AND TO ALSO SEE REPORTERS WHO
HAD SURROUNDED HIM TO, YOU KNOW,
TAKE PICTURES OR RECORD THAT
INTERVIEW, CRYING AS HE SPOKE
BECAUSE HE WAS SO EMOTIONAL.
WE WANTED TO PLAY A LITTLE BIT
MORE OF WHAT ROBBIE PARKER HAD
TO SAY, AS HE REMEMBERED HIS
DAUGHTER EMILIE IN THE MOST
HEART FELT AND TOUCHING WAYS.
LISTEN.
>> I WOULD REALLY LIKE TO OFFER
OUR DEEPEST CONDOLENCES TO ALL
THE FAMILIES WHO ARE DIRECTLY
AFFECTED BY THIS SHOOTING.
IT'S AN HORRIFIC TRAGEDY AND WE
WANT EVERYONE TO KNOW THAT OUR
HEARTS AND OUR PRAYERS GO OUT TO
THEM.
THIS INCLUDES THE FAMILY OF THE
SHOOTER.
I CAN'T IMAGINE HOW HARD THIS
EXPERIENCE MUST BE FOR YOU.
AND I WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT OUR
FAMILY AND OUR LOVE AND OUR
SUPPORT GOES OUT TO YOU AS WELL.
MY DAUGHTER EMILIE WOULD BE ONE
OF THE FIRST ONES TO BE STANDING
AND GIVING HER LOVE AND SUPPORT
TO ALL THOSE VICTIMS, BECAUSE
THAT'S THE TYPE OF PERSON THAT
SHE IS.
NOT BECAUSE OF ANY PARENTING
THAT MY WIFE AND I COULD HAVE
DONE, BUT BECAUSE THOSE WERE THE
GIFTS THAT WERE GIVEN TO HER BY
HER HEAVENLY FATHER.
I HAVE TWO REALLY GOOD FRIENDS
AT HOME WHO HAVE SET UP A
FACEBOOK PAGE TO HELP RAISE
MONEY FOR EMILIE.
AND WHEN I'VE GOTTEN ON THAT AND
JUST SEEN THE NUMBER OF PEOPLE
WHO HAVE EXPRESSED THEIR
CONDOLENCES, IT'S BEEN QUITE
OVERWHELMING.
AS THE DEEP PAIN SETS INTO OUR
HEARTS, WE FIND COMFORT ON THE
INCREDIBLE PERSON THAT EMILIE
WAS AND HOW MANY LIVES SHE WAS
ABLE TO TOUCH IN HER SHORT TIME
HERE ON EARTH.
EMILIE WAS BRIGHT, CREATIVE AND
VERY LOVING.
EMILIE WAS ALWAYS WILLING TO TRY
NEW THING, OTHER THAN FOOD.
SHE LOVED TO USE HER TALENTS TO
TOUCH THE LIVES OF EVERYONE THAT
SHE CAME INTO CONTACT WITH SHE
WAS AN EXCEPTIONAL ARTIST, AND
SHE ALWAYS CARRIED AROUND HER
MARKERS AND PENCILS SO THAT SHE
NEVER MISSED AN OPPORTUNITY TO
DRAW A PICTURE OF MAKE A CARD
FOR THOSE AROUND HER.
I CAN'T COUNT THE NUMBER OF
TIMES EMILIE NOTICED SOMEONE
FEELING SAD OR FRUSTRATED AND
WOULD RUSH TO FIND A PIECE OF
PAPER TO DRAW THEM A PICTURE OR
TO WRITE THEM AN ENCOURAGING
NOTE.
EMILIE'S CARD MAKING WAS
EXPRESSED BEAUTIFULFULLY THIS
LAST OCTOBER WHEN SHE PLACED A
VERY SPECIAL CARD THAT SHE HAD
MADE INTO THE CASKET WITH HER
GRANDPA WHO ALSO JUST RECENTLY
DIED OF A TRAGIC ACCIDENT.
EMILIE WAS A MENTOR TO HER TWO
LITTLE SISTERS DELIGHTING IN
TEACHING THEM HOW TO READ, DANCE
AND FIND THE SIMPLE JOYS IN
LIFE.
EMILIE'S LAUGHTER WAS
INFECTIOUS, AND ALL THOSE WHO
HAD THE PLEASURE TO MEET HER
WOULD AGREE THAT THIS WORLD IS A
BETTER PLACE BECAUSE SHE HAS
BEEN IN IT.
SHE WAS THEIR BEST FRIEND.
THEY WERE ALL BORN WITHIN THREE
YEARS OF EACH OTHER, SO BY LAW
THEY'RE VERY CLOSE.
SHE WAS TEACHING MY MIDDLE
DAUGHTER TO READ.
SHE WOULD HELP MY YOUNGEST
DAUGHTER LEARN HOW TO MAKE
THINGS, SHOW HER HOW TO DO
CRAFTS.
THEY LOOKED UP TO HER.
AND THEY LOOKED TO HER WHEN THEY
NEEDED COMFORT.
USUALLY THAT'S SAME FOR A MOM
AND A DAD, BUT IT WAS REALLY
SWEET TO SEE A TIME WHEN ONE OF
THEM WOULD FALL OR GET THEIR
FEELINGS HURT, HOW THEY WOULD
RUN TO EMILIE TO GET SUPPORT AND
HUGS AND KISSES.
SHE WAS THE TYPE OF PERSON WHO
COULD JUST LIGHT UP A ROOM.
SHE ALWAYS HAD SOMETHING KIND TO
SAY ABOUT ANYBODY.
AND HER LOVE AND THE STRENGTH
THAT SHE GAVE US AND THE EXAMPLE
THAT SHE SHOWED US IS
REMARKABLE.
SHE IS AN INCREDIBLE PERSON AND
I'M SO BLESSED TO BE HER DAD.
I WAS LEAVING TO WORK AND SHE
WOKE UP BEFORE I LEFT AND I'VE
ACTUALLY BEING TEACHING HER
PORTUGUESE AND SO OUR LAST
CONVERSATION WAS IN PORTUGUESE.
AND SHE TOLD ME GOOD MORNING AND
ASKED HOW I WAS DOING.
AND I SAID THAT I WAS DOING
WELL.
SHE SAID THAT SHE LOVED ME AND I
GAVE HER A KISS AND I WAS OUT
THE DOOR.
FREE AGENCY IS GIVEN TO ALL OF
US TO ACT AND CHOOSE WHATEVER WE
WANT AND GOD CAN'T TAKE THAT
AWAY FROM US.
I KNOW THAT'S SOMETHING HE WAS
GIVEN AND THAT'S SOMETHING HE
CHOSE TO DO WITH IT.
AND I KNOW GOD CAN'T TAKE THAT
AWAY.
I'M NOT MAD BECAUSE I HAVE MY
AGENCY TO MAKE SURE I USE THIS
EVENT TO DO WHAT I CAN, TO DO
WHATEVER I CAN.
TO WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT MY
FAMILY AND MY WIFE AND MY
DAUGHTERS ARE TAKEN CARE OF AND
THAT IF THERE'S ANYTHING THAT I
CAN DO TO HELP ANYBODY AT
ANYTIME, ANYWHERE, THAT I WOULD
BE WILLING TO DO THAT.
AS WE MOVE ON FROM WHAT HAPPENED
HERE, WHAT HAPPENED TO SO MANY
PEOPLE, LET IT NOT TURN INTO
SOMETHING THAT DEFINES US.
BUT SOMETHING THAT INSPIRES US
TO BE BETTER, TO BE MORE
COMPASSIONATE, AND MORE HUMBLE
PEOPLE.
>> COMMENTS FROM THE FATHER OF
6-YEAR-OLD EMILIE PARKER WHO WAS
ONE OF 20 CHILDREN WHO WERE
KILLED INSIDE THE SCHOOL THAT
DAY.
THE ROARS WHO WERE WATCHING HIS
REMARKS AND PEOPLE AT HOME
CRYING AS THEY HEARD WHAT HE HAD
TO SAY.
AND WHAT A SELFLESS THING TO
TALK ABOUT HOW HE WANTED TO BE
IN A POSITION TO HELP OTHER
PEOPLE EVEN WITH HIS OWN
DAUGHTER GONE.
LET'S GO RIGHT BACK TO DON.
>> IT IS SO HEART BREAKING.
IT'S ALMOST TOO MUCH TO TAKE.
I CAN'T IMAGINE HOW HE IS
STANDING, SOLEDAD.
LITTLE EMILIE WAS JUST ONE OF 20
CHILDREN, ALL OF THEM EITHER 6
OR 7 YEARS OLD.
MOST OF THEM GIRLS.
THEY WERE SHOT DEAD IN THEIR
SCHOOL YESTERDAY ALONG WITH SIX
TEACHERS AND STAFF BEFORE THE
KILLER SHOT HIMSELF.
AND CNN'S SUSAN CANDIOTTI IS
ALSO HERE IN NEWTOWN.
SHE'S GOT THE LATEST ON WHAT
PROGRESS THE POLICE ARE MAKING.
>> Reporter: INVESTIGATORS ARE
LEARNING MORE EACH DAY THAT MAY
EXPLAIN WHAT LED 20-YEAR-OLD
ADAM LANZA TO LAUNCH A VICIOUS
ATTACK ON YOUNG CHILDREN AND
ADULTS AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> OUR INVESTIGATORS AT THE
CRIME SCENE, THE SCHOOL, AND
SECONDARILY AT THE SECONDARY
CRIME SCENE THAT WAS DISCUSSED
DID PRODUCE SOME VERY -- A VERY
GOOD EVIDENCE IN THIS
INVESTIGATION.
THAT OUR INVESTIGATORS WILL BE
ABLE TO USE IN HOPEFULLY
PAINTING A COMPLETE PICTURE AS
TO HOW AND MORE IMPORTANTLY, WHY
THIS OCCURRED.
>> Reporter: POLICE WON'T SAY
WHAT THAT EVIDENCE IS, HOWEVER,
INVESTIGATORS HAVE BEEN CHECKING
OUT GUN RANGES AND SPORTING GOOD
STORES.
THEY FOLLOWED A LEAD THE SHOOTER
TRIED TO BUY A GUN TUESDAY AT
THIS LOCATION.
>> THERE'S NO INFORMATION THAT
SUBSTANTIATED THAT HE TRIED TO
ACQUIRE GUNS RECENTLY.
>> FEDERAL GUNS ALSO SAID THEY
COLLECTED WEAPONS AT THE HOME.
THREE MORE GUNS WERE FOUND.
THESE THREE RIFLE MODELS, ALL
OLDER.
THEY'RE BEING TRACED.
AT LEAST ONE HAS BEEN CONNECTED
TO THE MOTHER.
THREE MORE WEAPONS WERE
DISCOVERED WITH THE SHOOTER IN A
CLASSROOM WHERE HE TOOK HIS OWN
LIFE.
ACCORDING TO LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS, THE TWO HANDGUNS AND
SEMIAUTOMATIC LONG GUN CALLED A
BUSHMASTER WERE BOUGHT LEGALLY
BY HIS MOTHER.
THE CHIEF MEDICAL EXAMINER SAYS
THAT LONG GUN WAS USED TO KILL
SEVERAL VICTIMS.
>> I ONLY DID SEVEN OF THE
AUTOPSIES.
THE VICTIMS I HAD RANGED FROM
THREE TO 11 WOUBDS A PIECE AND I
ONLY SAW TWO OF THEM WITH
CLOSE-RANGE SHOOTING.
ALL OF THEM I KNOW WERE CAUSED
BY THE LONG WEAPON.
>> Reporter: ONE RELATIVE
DESCRIBES THE SHOOTER AS BEING A
VERY BRIGHT YOUNG MAN WHO AT
TIMES WAS HOME SCHOOLED BY HIS
MOTHER.
A LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIAL TELLS
US THAT HIS OLDER BROTHER SAYS
THAT HIS YOUNGER BROTHER WAS
AUTISTIC, BUT SO FAR NOTHING
ADDS UP TO A MOTIVE.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI, CNN, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> ALL RIGHT, SUSAN.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
AND UNDOUBTEDLY, THERE'S SOME
PROGRESS, BUT SOME QUESTIONS
WILL NEVER BE ANSWERED IN THIS
INVESTIGATION.
AND LET'S NOT FORGET, THOUGH,
THE FIRST VICTIM OF THIS
TRAGEDY.
THE MOTHER OF THE SHOOTER.
NEXT MORE ABOUT HER AND THE
WEAPONS THAT ENDED UP IN THE
HANDS OF HER TROUBLED SON.
QUESTIONS?
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Capella University understands
back from rough economic times.
Employees are being forced to do
more with less.
And the need for capable leaders
is greater than ever.
When you see these problems do
you take a step back,
or do you want to dive right in?
With a degree in business from
Capella University, you'll have
the knowledge to go further in
your career than you ever
thought possible.
Let's get started at CAPELLA.EDU
>> WELCOME BACK TO CNN'S
COVERAGE.
I'M DON LEMON ALONG WITH SOLEDAD
O'BRIEN.
WITH WITHIN JUST THE PAST FEW
HOURS IN THIS INVESTIGATION,
WE'VE LEARNED THE NAMES AND THE
AGES OF THE VICTIMS IN
YESTERDAY'S SHOOTING HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
SIX WOMEN AND 20 STUDENTS DIED
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
NOW, THAT NUMBER INCLUDES 12
GIRLS AND 8 BOYS.
16 OF THE KIDS WERE ONLY 6 YEARS
OLD.
THE OTHERS HAD TURNED 7 IN JUST
THE LAST FEW MONTHS.
THE FATHER OF THE ALLEGED
SHOOTER RELEASED A STATEMENT
TONIGHT.
PETER LANZA SAYS WORDS CANNOT
EXPRESS HIS FAMILY'S HEART
BREAK.
HE SAYS HIS FAMILY IS IN A,
QUOTE, STATE OF DISBELIEF.
WE ALSO LEARNED THAT PRESIDENT
BARACK OBAMA WILL BE COMING HERE
IN NEWTOWN TOMORROW TO MEET WITH
THE FAMILIESES OF THOSE KILLED.
AND SOLEDAD, REMEMBER JUST A FEW
MONTHS AGO, THE PRESIDENT HAVING
TO MEET WITH A FAMILY OF THE
VICTIMS IN COLORADO AND NOW HE'S
HAVING TO DO IT ALL OVER AGAIN
HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
>> DON, WE'RE GETTING A LITTLE
MORE DETAILS ABOUT THE
PRESIDENT'S SCHEDULE.
HE'LL MEET WITH THOSE FAMILIES
WHO LOST LOVED ONES.
THEN HE'LL MEET WITH FIRST
RESPONDERS.
BUT THEIR ACTIONS, ESPECIALLY IN
THE FACE OF WHAT THEY MUST HAVE
SEEN INSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
SO INCREDIBLY HEROIC.
THEN HE'LL CONTINUE ON WITH THIS
INTERFAITH MEETING HAPPENING
HERE.
WANT TO REMEMBER THE FIRST
VICTIM, THAT WOULD BE NANCY
LANZA.
SHE IS THE MOTHER OF THE
SHOOTER.
WE NOW KNOW SHE WAS KILLED BY
ONE OF HER OWN WEAPONS.
APPARENTLY SHE WAS A GUN
ENTHUSIAST.
BUT THERE ARE HAVE BEEN FEW
DETAILS BEYOND THAT THAT WE KNOW
OF HER.
DAVID, WHAT MORE DO WE KNOW
ABOUT THIS FIRST VICTIM?
.
>> WELL, ESSENTIALLY, THAT'S
WHAT WE CAME TO THIS AFFLUENT
NEIGHBORHOOD IN NEWTOWN TO FIND
OUT.
SORT OF THE RECURRING THEME THAT
WE SEEM TO GET IS SHE WAS JUST A
VERY PLEASANT PERSON TO BE
AROUND.
SHE WAS A BIG FAN OF GARDENING.
OFTEN LANDSCAPING IN HER
BACKYARD AND OFTEN TOOK TO A
GAME OF DICE THAT THE COMMUNITY
IN THIS AREA WOULD OFTEN HAVE A
FEW TIMES A MONTH.
REALLY DESCRIBED AS VERY MUCH A
TIGHT-KNIT COMMUNITY.
THAT IMAGE OF THIS WOMAN WHO
MOVED WITH HER FAMILY IN 1998,
EVENTUALLY DIVORCING HER HUSBAND
YEARS LATER, BUT RAISED HER TWO
BOYS IN THIS VERY PICK CHTURESQ
NEW ENGLAND TOWN IS COUNTERED BY
THIS PERSON WHO COLLECTED GUNS.
IN THE ONLY GUNS, BUT A
BUSHMASTER, A VERY HIGH POWERED
WEAPON, A GLOCK, THESE ARE
WEAPONS THAT SOME CONSIDER HIGH
POWERED.
SOME ARE JUST SORT OF YOUR RUN
OF THE MILL WEAPONS, BUT
NONETHELESS, A COLLECTION OF
WEAPONS HERE THAT AT TIMES CAN
SEEM SOMEWHAT AT ODDS WITH THIS
GARDENER WHO USED TO PLAY IN
PARLOR GAMES WITH LADIES NIGHT A
FEW TIMES A MONTH WITH THIS VERY
AFFLUENT COMMUNITY HERE.
AND IT'S HARD TO GET A SENSE OF
IT NOW, BUT MANY OF THESE HOUSES
HERE, TWO AND THREE-STORY HOMES,
QUITE AN AFFLUENT COMMUNITY.
MANY PEOPLE MOVE TO THIS AREA
BECAUSE OF THE SCHOOL DISTRICTS.
THAT SEEMS TO BE SOME OF THE
RECURRING THEMES WITH THE FAMILY
MEMBERS AND OTHER MEMBERS OF THE
NEIGHBORHOOD.
THEY FLOCK TO THIS NEIGHBORHOOD
BECAUSE OF THE VALUE OF THE
SCHOOL SYSTEMS.
SO AS TRAGIC AS THIS IS, IT HITS
A SPECIAL NOTE HERE IN NEWTOWN
BECAUSE OF THE DRAW, BECAUSE OF
THE SCHOOL SYSTEMS.
>> LET ME ASK YOU A QUESTION,
DAVID.
WAS THERE ANY INDICATION -- WE
KNOW SHE WAS A GUN ENTHUSIAST --
WAS THERE ANY INDICATION THAT'S
SOMETHING SHE SHARED WITH HER
SONS.
>> I'M SORRY, I COULDN'T QUITE
HEAR THAT.
>> I WANTED TO KNOW IF SHE IN
ANY WAY SHARED HER ENTHUSIASM
FOR WEAPONS AND IN SOME CASES
HIGH POWERED WEAPONS WITH EITHER
OF HER SONS, ONE THAT WE NOW
KNOW IS THE ALLEGED SHOOTNER
THIS CASE.
>> YOU KNOW, THAT'S AN
INTERESTING QUESTION.
WE HAVE BEEN GETTING CONFLICTING
REPORTS ABOUT THAT.
WE'RE TALKING TO THE FEDERAL
AGENCIES HERE IN THE AREA.
THERE ARE A NUMBER OF GUN RANGES
IN THIS AREA.
WE'VE SPOKEN TO SOP OF THE
DIRECTORS AT SOME OF THOSE
PLACES.
WE DO KNOW THAT WE DO KNOW THIS
WAS AN AREA THAT HER SON HAD
SHOT AT.
BUT ONE OF THE INDIVIDUALS THAT
I HAD SPOKEN TO EARLIER IN THE
DAY SAID THAT SHE DID SHOW HER
BRAND-NEW RIFLE.
FROM WHAT THIS INDIVIDUAL SAID,
SHE TOOK THEM TO TARGET
SHOOTING.
THAT'S CONTRADICTED BY WHAT SOME
OF THESE AUTHORITIES ARE SAYING
FROM THE ATF, FROM THE FBI.
SO IT'S A BIT OF A MUDDLED
PICTURE EXACTLY HOW SHE USED
THESE WEAPONS, WHETHER THEY WERE
JUST SIMPLY COLLECTOR ITEMS THAT
SAT IN HER HOUSE OR WHETHER SHE
WAS OUT THERE USING THEM ON
ABFREQUENT BASIS.
REGARDLESS, THERE WERE SIX
WEAPONS THAT POTENTIALLY COULD
HAVE BEEN USED BY THE SHOOTER.
AND UNFORTUNATELY HE DID GET HIS
HANDS ON SOME OF THEM AND MADE
USE OF THEM.
>> INCOMPLETE PORTRAIT OF NANCY
LANZA TO REPORT TO FOLKS.
THANKS FOR THAT UPDATE.
LET'S GET BACK TO DON LEMON.
>> ALL RIGHT, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
THE DEBATE OVER GUN CONTROL, AND
THE SECOND AMENDMENT TO THE
CONSTITUTION, MOST PEOPLE THINK
THAT THEY KNOW WHAT IT SAYS, BUT
HERE'S THE ACTUAL TEXT.
WE'LL PUT IT UP.
YOU DECIDE FOR YOURSELF WHAT
RIGHT IT GUARANTEES.
A WELL REGULATED MILITIA.
THERE IT IS.
A WELL REGULATED MILITIA, BEING
NECESSARY TO THE SECURITY OF A
FREE STATE.
THE RIGHT OF THE PEOPLE TO KEEP
AND BEAR ARMS SHALL NOT BE
INFRINGED.
YOU KNOW, THIS TRAGEDY WILL ONCE
AGAIN FUEL THE DEBATE OVER OUR
RIGHT TO BEAR ARMS IN THIS
COUNTRY.
AND JUST HOW MUCH REGULATION
SHOULD THERE BE REGARDING THE
ACCESSIBILITY OF GUNS.
I WANT TO BRING IN NOW A FORMER
POLICE OFFICER, AND HE'S NOW THE
DIRECTOR OF THE LEAD
INTELLIGENCE AND PROTECTIONS A
NEW YORK-BASED COMPANY.
NO ONE IS TALKING ABOUT REMOVING
THE RIGHT TO BEAR ARMS.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT THIS, IT SAYS A
WELL REGULATED MILITIA, BEING
NECESSARY FOR THE SECURITY OF A
FREE STATE, THE RIGHT OF THE
PEOPLE TO KEEP AND BEAR ARMS
SHALL NOT BE INFRINGED.
THAT DOES NOT MEAN THAT YOU CAN
GO OUT AND BUY AS MANY WEAPONS
AS POSSIBLE AND GO OUT AND BE
ABLE TO SHOOT PEOPLE.
IT'S TALKING ABOUT IF THE
GOVERNMENT BECOMES A TYRANNY, IS
THAT NOT CORRECT?
>> THAT'S PART OF THE THEORY.
I MEAN, TO BE ABLE TO KEEP THE
CITIZENS FREE IF THE CLIMATE OR
MENTALITY OF THE GOVERNMENT
CHANGES.
BUT THESE ARE WEAPONS BY PEOPLE
WHO ARE NOT STABLE.
I SUPPORT THE SECOND AMENDMENT.
THE PROBLEM IS WE'RE HAVING
PEOPLE ACQUIRE FIREARMS IN OUR
COUNTRY TODAY WHO ARE HAVING ME
MOTIONALLY.
THE VETTING PROCESS FOR US IN
LAW ENFORCEMENT INCLUDES
PSYCHOLOGICAL SCREENING BEFORE
THEY GIVE US A HANDGUN.
THAT SAME STANDARD DOES NOT
APPLY TO OTHER PEOPLE IN THE
UNITED STATES.
WE CAN JUST WALK IN WITH A
DRIVER'S LICENSE, NOT KNOW YOU
FROM A HOLE IN THE GROUND AND IN
TWO DAYS, AS IN WISCONSIN,
ACQUIRE A HANDGUN.
THIS IS THE PROBLEM.
>> WE HAVE TO EVOLVE WITH THE
TIMES.
THIS WAS A DIFFERENT AMERICA
WHEN WE WROTE THIS AMENDMENT TO
THE CONSTITUTION.
AND I THINK WE NEED TO HID A
CHORD OF SENSIBILITY AND DECENCY
AND UNDERSTAND THAT WE NEED TO
BE PLIABLE AND COME TO
COMPROMISE.
THAT APPLIES TO BOTH EXTREMES
HERE, THE NRA, WHOSE PHILOSOPHY
IS IF YOU CAN SEE LIGHTNING AND
HEAR THUNDER YOU SHOULD GET A
GUN AND A LIBERAL WHO THINKS
WE'RE GOING TO GET RID OF 300
MILLION GUNS.
>> DURING THE COLORADO SHOOTING,
THE THEATRE MASSACRE.
I WENT, IN 20 MINUTES WAS ABLE
TO BUY AN AR-15 AND ALL THE
AMMUNITION THAT WENT ALONG WITH
IT BY JUST SHOWING A DRIVER'S
LICENSE AND FEELING OUT A PAPER
WORK.
>> THAT'S NOT THE PROBLEM, A
SYMPTOM OF THE PROBLEM.
AMERICANS ARE SCARED TODAY, TOO.
WHEN YOU TURN ON THE TV AND
EVERY OTHER MINUTE WE'RE
LISTENING TO SHOOTINGS IN MOVIE
THEATRES, YOU'RE WONDERING CAN
YOU BRING YOUR CHILDREN TO A
MOVIE THEATRE.
CHRISTMAS TIME YOU THINK YOUR
FAMILY AND CHILDREN ARE SAFE AT
MALLS.
SCHOOL, TEXAS A&M, VIRGINIA
TECH.
NOW IN GRAMMAR SCHOOL.
WHAT'S HAPPENING IS WE'RE
AFFECTING THE PSYCHE OF THE
AVERAGE AMERICAN.
AND WHAT THEY'RE DOING IS NAY
EAR KNEE-JERK REACTING BY GOING
OUT AND ACQUIRING THIS TOOL THAT
THEY THINK IS GOING TO KEEP THEM
SAFE, WHICH IN THEORY IT WILL
WITH PROPER TRAINING, WHICH VERY
FEW PEOPLE ARE RECEIVING EXCEPT
US IN LAW ENFORCEMENT.
>> AND THERE ARE TWO DIFFERENT
SCHOOLS OF THOUGHT HERE, THERE'S
TWO DIFFERENT REALITIES.
THE CULTURAL VIOLENCE FOR PEOPLE
WHO DO NOT HAVE RESPECT FOR
GUNS.
THEN THERE ARE PEOPLE LIKE YOU
WHO GO OUT, THEY LEARN ABOUT
GUNS, THEY HANDLE THEM AND
THEY'RE VERY KNOWLEDGEABLE ABOUT
GUNS.
SO THE DISCONNECT HERE IS WHAT?
>> EDUCATION.
YOU SEE, WE BECOME EDUCATED IN
HOW TO HANDLE AND MANAGE THESE
THINGS.
KIND OF LIKE THIS ISSUE ABOUT
SAFEGUARDING THEM.
THIS IS THE SECOND SHOOTING IN A
WEEK THAT WE'VE HAD SOMEONE
ACQUIRE A GUN BECAUSE OF SOMEONE
FAILING TO PROPERLY SAFEGUARD
THESE WEAPONS.
>> WHAT ABOUT THE RESPONSIBILITY
OF PEOPLE WHO OWN THE GUNS.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
IN LAW ENFORCEMENT IT'S
IMPRESSED UPON US THE NEED TO
SAFEGUARD OUR WEAPONS AND
THERE'S A SEVERE PENALTY IF YOU
LOSE ONE.
IF YOU THINK PUTTING IT IN THE
TOP DRESSER DRAWER IN YOUR HOME
IS SAFEGUARDING IT.
WHEN SOMEONE BREAKS IN AND TAKES
IT, THE PENALTY IS EXTREME.
>> IN COLORADO, I THINK GUN
OWNERSHIP AND APPLICATIONSHAVE
GONE UP BY 40% WITHIN JUST THE
LAST YEAR OR SO?
>> GUN SALES IN GENERAL ARE
GOING THROUGH THE ROOF.
ESPECIALLY SINCE THE PRESIDENT
WAS ELECTED.
YOU KNOW, THIS IS THE DYNAMIC
THAT'S GOING ON IN AMERICA.
SOO.
>> THAT REMINDS ME OF THE THING,
HE'S COMING TO GET YOUR GUNS.
NO ONE HAS PROPOSED ANY
LEGISLATION ON ANY SAID SIDE AND
THIS PRESIDENT HAS NOT COME TO
GET ANYBODY'S GUNS.
>> I ALWAYS HEARD THIS PRESIDENT
VERY INTELLIGENTLY MAKE A REMARK
WHEN LEFS CHALLENGED ABOUT
REINSTATING THE 1994 CLINTON
ASSAULT RIFLE BAN, HE SAID THE
FOLLOWING -- WE'RE GOING TO
FOCUS ON ENFORCEMENT.
THAT'S THE KEY.
BUT THERE'S A PROBLEM INHERENT
TO THAT, BECAUSE YOU NEED
RESOURCES TO DO THAT, DON.
YOU'VE GOT TO HAVE PERSONNEL AND
YOU'VE GOT TO HAVE MONEY TO
SUPPORT THAT.
AND ALL THESE THINGS WE'RE
EXPERIENCING LIKE GUN SHOWS
WHERE YOU CAN WALK IN, WALK OUT
REQUIRES AN ENFORCEMENT
MECHANISM.
YOU'VE GOT TO HAVE MONEY AND
YOU'VE GOT TO HAVE PERSONNEL TO
ENFORCE THAT.
IT'S A COMPLICATED PROBLEM.
BUT I HAVE TO SAY THIS TO YOU,
DON.
EVEN IF WE REINSTITUTE THE
CLINTON ASSAULT RIFLE BAN IN
1994, I DON'T THINK IT'S GOING
TO CHANGE THINGS.
THERE'S SO MUCH IGNORANCE IN THE
WAY WE DEVELOP THESE LAWS AND A
LACK OF FAMILIARITY ON HOW TO GO
TOWARD WITH IT, YOU CAN CHOKE ON
IT.
>> AND IT'S SO PLITIZED.
WHEN PEOPLE TALK ABOUT TAKING A
LOOK AT GUN LAWS IN THIS
COUNTRY, NO ONE IS SAYING TAKE
AWAY YOUR RIGHT TO BEAR ARMS.
THIS IS NOT A LEFT OR RIGHT --
WELL, IT IS.
IT'S ACTUALLY A LEFT AND RIGHT
ISSUE AND IN BETWEEN.
IT'S AN INTELLIGENT ARGUMENT OR
CONVERSATION THAT WE SHOULD BE
HAVING, NOT ONE ABOUT WHICH SIDE
OF THE POLITICAL AISLE YOU'RE
ON.
>> THE THING I WILL SAY TO YOU
IS ALL I WANT STOOD IS KNOW A
LITTLE BIT MORE ABOUT YOU OTHER
THAN THE FACT THAT YOU HAVEN'T
BEEN ARRESTED.
I THINK THAT'S REASONABLE.
AND I WOULD DEBATE THIS WITH THE
NRA UNTIL THE COWS CAME HOME.
AND ON THE OTHER SIDE OF THE
FENCE, THE EXTREME LEFT LIBERAL
PEOPLE THAT THINK THEY'RE GOING
TO WAVE A MAGIC WAND AND MAKE
300 MILLION WEAPONS YOU'RE AWARE
OF GO AWAY.
>> YOU'RE GOING TO CREATE A
BLACK MARKET.
>> NEW YORK HAS THE MOST
RESTRICTIVE GUN LAWS IN THE
UNITED STATES.
WE HAVE VERY GOOD GUN LAWS.
WE NOW HAVE THE BIGGEST BLACK
MARKET FOR THEM ALSO.
THEY FILTER IN FROM GEORGIA,
VIRGINIA, ARIZONA.
YOU KNOW, WE KNOW WHERE THEY'RE
COMING FROM.
I GO BACK AND SAY WHAT I'VE SAID
BEFORE, UH YO EVE GOT TO HAVE
RESOURCES TO GO IN AND ARREST
THAT PROBLEM AND WE DON'T HAVE
IT.
>> AND THE PRESIDENT SAYS WE
NEED TO HAVE MEANINGFUL CHANGES
IN THIS COUNTRY WHEN IT COMES TO
GUN LAWS AND A MEANINGFUL
CONVERSATION.
AND THAT MEANS NOT POLITICIZING
IT IN WASHINGTON.
>> WE NEED COMPROMISE.
>> THANK YOU.
>> MY PLEASURE AS ALWAYS.
>> MOST OF US CAN'T EVEN IMAGINE
WHAT THE PEOPLE HERE IN NEWTOWN
ARE GOING THROUGH RIGHT NOW.
BUT TIN WE SPOKE TO SOME PEOPLE
DIDN'T HAVE TO IMAGINE IT.
YEARS AGO.
COLUMBINE SURVIVORS TALK ABOUT
HOW THEY GOT THROUGH THEIR
TRAGEDY IN 1999.
PEOPLE HAVE DOUBTS
ABOUT TAKING ASPIRIN FOR PAIN.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
SINCE AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL
WAS FOUNDED BACK IN 1894,
THEY'VE BEEN COMMITTED
TO PUTTING CLIENTS FIRST.
HELPING GENERATIONS
THROUGH TOUGH TIMES.
GOOD TIMES.
NEVER TAKING A BAILOUT.
THERE WHEN YOU NEED THEM.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
OVER THE CENTURIES.
THE STRENGTH OF
A GLOBAL FINANCIAL LEADER.
THE HEART OF
A ONE-TO-ONE RELATIONSHIP.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
TO TAKE A CENTRUM SILVER
MULTIVITAMIN EVERY DAY.
I TOLD HIM, SURE.
CAN'T HURT, RIGHT?
THEN I HEARD THIS NEWS
ABOUT A MULTIVITAMIN STUDY
LOOKING AT LONG-TERM
HEALTH BENEFITS FOR MEN OVER 50.
THE ONE THEY USED
IN THAT STUDY...
CENTRUM SILVER.
THAT'S WHAT I TAKE.
MY DOCTOR!
HE KNOWS HIS STUFF.
[ Male Announcer ] CENTRUM.
THE MOST RECOMMENDED.
MOST PREFERRED.
MOST STUDIED.
CENTRUM,
ALWAYS YOUR MOST COMPLETE.
>> PEOPLE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT ARE TRYING TO COME
TO GRIPS WITH THE TRAGEDY THAT
HAPPENED HERE.
W45 CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT THE
PEOPLE WHOSE LOSS IS BEING FELT
IN THE COMMUNITY.
>> THEY REALLY EMPLY FIED WHAT
NEWTOWN AND SANDY HOOK AND SANDY
HOOK SCHOOL MEAN TO US.
SAN DPI HOOK, ALL THREE OF MY
CHILDREN WEPT THERE.
AND IT IS A VERY SPECIAL SCHOOL.
IT WON A VANGUARD AWARD A FEW
YEARS AGO FOR INNOVATION.
I KNEW THE FORMER PRINCIPAL AND
MY YOUNGEST CHILD WAS THERE
WHEN -- I'M SORRY.
WHEN THIS PRINCIPLE WORKED
THERE.
SHE WAS UNLIKE A LOT OF
ADMINISTRATORS.
SHE DIDN'T HAVE A FORMALITY TO
HER.
SHE HAD A BIG, BEAUTIFUL SMILE
THAT YOU CAN SEE IN THOSE
PICTURES.
I THINK SHE REALLY PROVED ON
FRIDAY THAT SHE HAD THE
CHILDREN'S BEST INTEREST AT
HEART.
WHAT HAPPENS NEXT IN THIS
COMMUNITY?
I DON'T THINK ANYBODY ANYWHERE
COULD IMAGINE THIS SORT OF
TRAGEDY HAPPENING.
HOW DO YOU HEAL FROM THAT?
>> WE BAND TOGETHER AS A
COMMUNITY.
THIS TOWN IS 300 YEARS OLD AND
IT'S BEEN, YOU KNOW, IT'S GOING
TO GO ON.
WE WILL SUPPORT EACH OTHER AS WE
ALWAYS HAVE DONE.
WE'LL BE HERE FOR THE FAMILIES
AND WE'LL PULL TOGETHER.
I THINK THERE'S A LOT OF ALL OF
THAT IN THIS TOWN AND WE'LL BE
OKAY.
>> THANK YOU FOR TALKING WITH
US.
THANKS FOR COMING OUT TO TALK TO
THIS IS A VERY COMMON THEME FROM
MANY OF THE FAMILIES THAT WE'VE
HAD A CHANCE TO TALK TO TODAY,
DON.
THE CHURCH OVER MY SHOULDER,
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN STREAMING IN
ALL NIGHT.
THEY DON'T HAVE A FORMAL SERVICE
THIS EVENING.
PEOPLE SIT AND CAN BE TOGETHER.
NOT JUST HERE BUT AT MANY
CHURCHES IN THE AREA HAVE REALLY
OPENED UP THEIR DOORS AND
THEY'RE TRYING TO SPIRITUAL LIVE
BRING THIS COMMUNITY TOGETHER.
DON, BACK TO YOU.
PRESIDENT BARACK OBAMA WILL BE
HERE TOMORROW.
THE WHITE HOUSE SAYS THE
PRESIDENT WANTS TO MEET THE
FAMILY OF THE 20 KIDS AND SIX
ADULTS WHO WERE KILLED IN THEIR
SCHOOL YESTERDAY.
AS FOR THE MAN WHO ALLEGEDLY
KILLED ALL THOSE PEOPLE, POLICE
SAY THEY'RE MAKING PROGRESS,
PIECING TOGETHER WHAT MAY HAVE
DRIVEN ADAM LANZA TO SUCH AN
HORRIFIC ACT.
THEY'VE BEEN TO HIS HOME WHERE
HE ALLEGEDLY KILLED HIS MOTHER.
EVERY VICTIM WAS HIT BY MORE
THAN ONE SHOT.
SOME OF THEM WERE SHOT MORE THAN
10 TIMES.
POLICE FOUND THREE GUNS BESIDES
THE SUSPECT'S BODY.
HOW VICTIMS OF THE COLUMBINE
SHOOTING ARE MOURNING.
THE COLUMBINE MASSACRE, 14 YEARS
AGO, SOME ARE NOW PARENTS
THEMSELVES.
>> YOU LOSE THE SENSE THAT
THINGS COULD NEVER HAPPEN TO
YOU.
SO MANY PARENTS WOULD SAY, THIS
WOULD NEVER HAPPEN TO MY CHILD'S
SCHOOL.
WELL, FOR ME AS A PARENT OF A
CHILD, I BELIEVE THIS COULD
EASILY HAPPEN AT MY CHILD'S
SCHOOL.
THAT'S BECAUSE IT HAS HAPPENED
TO ME BEFORE.
I WOULD HOPE THAT THE PEOPLE
INVOLVED WILL WALK BESIDE THESE
CHILDREN AND THE FAMILIES FOR
YEARS TO COME.
THEY HAVE YEARS AND YEARS OF
HEALING THAT THEY'RE GOING TO BE
CHASING.
I HOPE WE CAN COME BESIDE THEM
AND ENCOURAGE THEM AND FOCUS
POSITIVELY ON THE LIVES OF THE
ONES THAT WERE LOST.
I WANT YOU TO MEET SHAWN GRAVES.
HE WAS SHOT SIX TIMES.
HE ENDED UP IN A WHEELCHAIR AND
TO THIS DAY, HE HAS PAIN BECAUSE
OF IT.
I SPOKE WITH HIM ABOUT HOW THE
NEWS OF CONNECTICUT WAS
AFFECTING HIM.
>> I LIVE WITH PAIN PHYSICALLY
ON A DAILY BASIS BECAUSE OF
INJURIES I SUSTAINED.
BUT LOOKING BACK THEN, I TRY NOT
TO THINK ABOUT IT.
BUT WHEN SOMETHING LIKE THIS
HAPPENS, THAT'S THE FIRST THING
YOU DO, YOU BEGIN TO RELIVE IT.
TURNING ON THE NEWS AND JUST
WATCHING THE COVERAGE LOIF FROM
THIS POINT OF VIEW VERSUS WHERE
I WAS THEN.
IT WILL TAKE YOU THROUGH AN
EMOTIONAL TOLL, THAT'S FOR SURE.
A LOT WERE REACHING OUT TO
FAMILIES AFTER MASS SHOOTINGS.
AND THEY WERE JUST AMONG THE
MANY AROUND THE WORLD WHO ARE
MOURNING IN THE WAKE OF THIS
TRAGEDY.
>> ONE OF THOSE REACHING OUT IS
A SURVIVOR OF THE COLUMBINE
MASSACRE AND IS ALSO A
FILMMAKER.
THE FILM THAT HE'S MADE IS
CALLED "COLUMBINE WOUNDED
MINDS."
HE'S WITH US.
IT'S NICE TO TALK TO YOU.
WHEN YOU FIRST SAW THIS
UNFOLDING LOOV, WE HEARD FROM A
YOUNG MAN WHO SAID IT ALL CAME
BACK TO HIM.
IT'S JUST HORRIFYING TO SEE IT
UNFOLD.
I HAVE TO IMAGINE FOR ANYBODY
WHO SURVIVES SOMETHING SIMILAR,
IT MUST BE THE VERY SAME THING
FOR YOU, THAT YOU SORT OF FLASH
BACK TO THAT MOMENT AT
COLUMBINE.
IS THAT TRUE?
>> YEAH, ABSOLUTELY.
I MEAN, IT'S COMPLETELY NUMBING,
YOU KNOW, RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
SORT OF -- AT FIRST, WHEN I
TURNED ON THE TV AND I SAW IT,
IT WAS A FEELING OF DENIAL.
I DIDN'T REALLY BELIEVE THAT IT
WAS HAPPENING AGAIN.
AND THEN, YOU KNOW, YOU START
GETTING THE TEXTS AND THE
E-MAILS, PHONE CALLS AND IT JUST
SORT OF SINKS IN AND I START
RELIVING ALL THOSE MOMENTS ALL
OVER AGAIN.
>> TELL ME ABOUT THE FILM THAT
YOU MADE.
I THINK THERE ARE LESSONS IN
THAT FILM THAT COULD BE HELPFUL
TO THE PEOPLE WHO ARE HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
WHAT'S THE FILM ABOUT?
>> I'M MAKING A FILM PROJECT
THAT BASICALLY HELPS THE FUTURE
LOOK BETTER FOR THOSE WHO
SURVIVE THROUGH THESE KINDS OF
TRAGEDIES.
BECAUSE WHAT I WANT THROUGH FOR
COME LUM BIEN, I WAS A JUNIOR AT
THE TIME AND I WAS IN THE
CAFETERIA.
I LOST A BUNCH OF FRIENDS.
I WENT THROUGH SOME PRETTY
HORRIFIC THINGS, I DIDN'T THINK
THERE WAS SOMETHING WRONG WITH
ME.
I FELT IT WAS 10 YEARS BEFORE I
FELT THERE WAS ANYTHING I NEEDED
TO HAVE WORKED ON.
YOU KNOW, I WENT BACK TO REACH
OUT TO MY COMMUNITY AND TO SEE
WHAT KIND OF HELP THERE WAS
STILL THERE FOR US.
IT DRIED UP MANY, MANY, MANY
YEARS AGO.
SO THIS IS TO TRY AND FIND SOME
SORT OF SOLUTION FOR THOSE
LONG-TERM HEALING EFFECTS FOR
LARGE COMMUNITIES.
BECAUSE IT'S REALLY HARD TO GET
INDIVIDUAL HELP FOR THIS AMOUNT
OF PEOPLE.
WHAT I'M FINDING IS ALL THESE
COMMUNITIES ARE REALLY THE
ANSWER TO ALL THESE THINGS.
SO THIS IS WHAT THAT FILM IS
ABOUT, FINDING THOSE COMMUNITIES
AND FINDING THE ANSWERS TO THIS
LONG-TERM HEALING.
>> IT SEEMS LOOIC A MESSAGE FOR
THOSE WHO TRY TO DECIDE, DO DO
THEY GET COUNSELING, DO THEY
TAKE ADVANTAGE OF THE COUNSELING
THAT'S HERE AND NOW.
YOU WOULD SAY YES BECAUSE, YOU
KNOW, ALL THOSE YEARS DOWN THE
READ, IT MAY NOT BE THERE.
AND YOU WILL BE DEALING WITH
SOME SERIOUS CHALLENGES.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
COUNSELING FOR ME RIGHT OFF THE
BAT, IT WAS DIFFICULT.
I WAS IN A ROOM I WASN'T REALLY
FAMILIAR WITH AND I WASN'T
COMFORTABLE SHARING ME THE MOST.
REACHING OUT TO FRIENDS AND
FAMILY, THOSE ARE THE PEOPLE
THAT ARE GOING TO GET YOU
THROUGH THIS IN THE LONG RUN.
DOWN THE ROAD YOU'RE GOING TO
FOCUS ON THE PEOPLE THAT YOU
CONNECT WITH IN THE BEGINNING.
SO THAT'S THE MAIN THING.
GO OUT AND GET SOME THERAPY IF
YOU REALLY NEED IT.
BUT THE BEST THING YOU CAN DO IS
JUST BE THERE WITH THE ONES YOU
LOVE.
>> THANK YOU FOR TALKING TO US.
WE APPRECIATE YOUR TIME.
WANT TO GO BACK TO DON LEMON.
>> ALL RIGHT, SOLEDAD, THANK
YOU.
THERE ARE STORIES OF HEROISM
THAT COME OUT OF THE TRAGEDY IN
NEWTOWN.
WITHIN OF THOSE STORIES IS NEXT.
[ Female Announcer ]
IMAGINE SKIN SO HEALTHY,
IT NEVER GETS DRY AGAIN.
CAN YOUR MOISTURIZER DO THAT?
[ Female Announcer ]
DERMATOLOGIST RECOMMENDED
Aveeno HAS AN OAT FORMULA,
NOW PROVEN
TO BUILD A MOISTURE RESERVE,
SO SKIN CAN REPLENISH ITSELF.
THAT'S HEALTHY SKIN FOR LIFE.
ONLY FROM Aveeno.
HE LOVES RISK.
BUT WHETHER
HE'S CLIMBING EVEREST,
SCUBA DIVING THE
GREAT BARRIER REEF WITH SHARKS,
OR JUMPING INTO THE MARKET,
HE GOES WITH PEOPLE HE TRUSTS,
WHICH IS WHY HE TRADES
WITH A COMPANY
THAT DOESN'T NICKEL AND DIME
HIM WITH HIDDEN FEES.
SO HE CAN WORRY
ABOUT OTHER THINGS,
LIKE WHAT THE MARKET IS DOING
AND BEING READY,
NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENS,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE,
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
BUT I'M STILL STUBBED UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus Liquid Gels
SPEEDS RELIEF
TO YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A DECONGESTANT
FOR YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
THANKS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
>>> LET'S GET A QUICK UPDATE ON
THIS STORY FOR YOU.
TOMORROW WILL BE ANOTHER
EMOTIONAL DAY HERE IN NEWTOWN.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL TRAVEL HERE
TO MEET WITH THE VICTIM'S
FAMILIES.
HE'S ALSO GOING TO ATTEND AN
INTERFAITH VIGIL SCHEDULED FOR
TOMORROW EVENING.
POLICE HERE SAY THEY ARE FINDING
WHAT THEY CALL VERY GOOD
EVIDENCE IN THEIR INVESTIGATION.
THEY ALSO SAY A WOMAN WHO WAS
WOUNDED AT THE SCHOOL IS
PROVIDING INFORMATION AND WILL
BE, QUOTE, INSTRUMENTAL TO THE
INVESTIGATION.
THE FATHER OF THE SHOOTER HAS
RELEASED A STATEMENT.
PETER LANZA SAYS WORDS CANNOT
EXPRESS HIS FAMILY'S HEART
BREAK.
HE SAYS THE FAMILY IS IN WHAT HE
CALLS A STATE OF DISBELIEF.
PETER LANZA'S EX-WIFE NANCY WAS
THE FIRST VICTIM.
POLICE BELIEVE HER SON SHOT HER
AT HER HOME BEFORE HEADING TO
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
NANCY LANZA WAS A GUN COLLECTOR
AND THE GUNS USED IN THE
SHOOTINGS BELONGED TO HER.
LET'S SEND IT BACK NOW TO
SOLEDAD.
>> DON, THANK YOU.
THERE WAS A VIGIL TONIGHT FOR
VICTORIA SOTO, ONE OF THE VERY
FIRST VICTIMS THAT WAS ANNOUNCED
PUBLICLY AND IDENTIFIED
PUBLICLY.
27 YEARS OLD, A FIRST GRADE
TEACHER.
AND SHE WAS KILLED, SHOT AND
KILLED IN HER CLASSROOM.
BUT SHE'S BEING HAILED TODAY AS
A HERO.
KATE BOLDUAN SPOKE TO A COUPLE,
SOME PARENTS WHO SAY THEY
BELIEVE THAT THEIR SON'S LIFE
MAY HAVE BEEN SAVED BECAUSE OF
THIS YOUNG TEACHER.
>> ROBERT AND DIANE LAKONA HAS
TWO CHILDREN AT THAT ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL YESTERDAY, A
SECOND-GRADER AND THEIR SON IN
FIRST GRADE WHO THEY SAY IT IS A
MIRACLE HE MADE IT OUT ALIVE
AFTER COMING FACE TO FACE WITH
THE SHOOTER.
>> THAT'S WHEN THEY HEARD NOISES
THAT THEY INITIALLY THOUGHT WERE
HAMMERS FALLING.
THEN THEY REALIZED THAT IT WAS
GUNSHOTS.
AND MS. SOTO, WHO WAS ADEN'S
TEACHER, HAD THE PRESENCE OF
MIND TO MOVE ALL THE CHILDREN TO
A DISTANCE AWAY FROM THE FLOOR
ON THE SIDE OF THE ROOM FURTHEST
AWAY FROM THE DOOR.
THAT'S WHEN THE GUNMAN BURST IN,
DID NOT SAY A WORD, NO FACIAL
EXPRESSIONS, AND PROCEEDED TO
SHOOT THEIR TEACHER.
AND THEY BASICALLY RAN RIGHT
NEXT TO THE GUY AND OUT THE
DOOR.
>> THEY RAN PAST THE GUNMAN.
>> THEY RAN PAST THE GUY.
HE'S STILL STANDING IN THE DOOR
AND THEY RAN PAST HIM AND RAN
DOWN THE HALLWAY AND THEY'RE ONE
OF THE CLOSEST ROOMS TO THE MAIN
ENTRANCE.
AND ADEN WAS -- HAD THE PRESENCE
OF MIND TO HOLD THE DOOR FOR ONE
OF HIS CLASSMATES.
THERE WAS ANOTHER ONE OF HIS
CLASSMATES THAT WAS A LITTLE
BEHIND.
WAITED FOR HIM AND THEY RAN OUT
TO THE MAIN ROAD.
>> WE KNOW HIS TEACHER,
VICTORIA, SOTO, DIED IN THAT
CLASSROOM TRYING TO PROTECT HER
STUDENTS.
HE KNOWS HIS TEACHER WAS SHOT.
DO YOU THINK HE KNOWS THAT SHE
LIKELY DID NOT MAKE IT?
>> HE KEEPS ASKING ABOUT HER.
I THINK HE'S REASSURING HIMSELF
THAT SHE'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
HE REALLY, REALLY CARED ABOUT
HIS TEACHER.
HE WAS VERY CLOSE WITH HER.
AND SHE REALLY LOVED THAT CLASS.
AND HE KEEPS SAYING, I REALLY
HOPE SHE'S OKAY, I HOPE IT'S NOT
HER.
HE KNOWS THAT SHE'S BEEN HURT
BUT HE DOESN'T KNOW THE END
RESULT.
HE KNOWS THE KIDS THAT HE SAW
GETTING SHOT.
HEP DOESN'T KNOW THE OUTCOME.
SO I THINK HE'S REASSURING
HIMSELF IN HIS 6-YEAR-OLD MIND.
I KNOW HE'S PROCESSING IT.
BUT I THINK HE'S REASSURING
HIMSELF.
I THINK HE'S TELLING HIMSELF
THAT IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
WE HAD TO PUT THE SIGN OUT IN
THE FRONT TODAY ASKING PEOPLE
NOT TO RING THE DOORBELL BECAUSE
HE STILL HASN'T INTERNALIZED THE
FACT THAT THIS GUNMAN, THIS BAD
GUY IS GONE.
AND HE WANTS TO KNOW IF THERE
ARE MORE BAD GUYS IN THE WORLD.
AND I DON'T KNOW HOW TO ANSWER
THAT QUESTION PROPERLY AND SO
WHEN SOMEONE RINGS THE DOORBELL,
HE THINKS IT'S HIM COMING TO,
COMING FOR HIM.
AND SO HE -- SO I THINK OUR
BIGGEST CONCERN NOW IS MAKING
SURE THAT WE HANDLE HIS
SENSITIVE NATURE PROPERLY AND
CAREFULLY AND SUPPORT HIM AND
SUPPORT OUR DAUGHTER BECAUSE SHE
AGAIN DOES PROCESS THINGS VERY
DIFFERENTLY THAN HE DOES.
SO THAT'S OUR JOB AS PARENTS NOW
IS TO STAY CLOSE TO THEM, HOLD
THEM, HUG THEM, LOVE THEM AND
LET THEM KNOW THAT THEY ARE
SAFE.
>> THEY DID NOT WANT THEIR
CHILDREN TO BE PART OF THE
INTERVIEW.
BUT I DID SPEND TIME WITH THEM
THIS MORNING.
AND ADEN AND HIS SISTER, THEY
SEEMED IN HIGH SPIRITS.
BUT CLEARLY SHAKEN.
AND AS HARD AS IT HAS BEEN FOR
THIS FAMILY, THEY SAY THAT THEIR
HEARTS GO OUT TO THE SO MANY
OTHER FAMILIES WHO CANNOT GO
HOME AND HUG THEIR CHILDREN
TONIGHT.
>> KATE, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THAT FAMILY OBVIOUSLY HURTING
TONIGHT LIKE MANY OTHERS ARE.
THE REVEREND DAVID SPENCER IS A
CHAPLAIN AND A GRIEF COUNSELOR
AND WENDY WALSH IS A HUMAN
BEHAVIORAL SPECIALIST.
THEY BOTH JOIN ME NOW.
THANKS FOR JOINING US ON SUCH A
REALLY HORRIFIC EVENT HERE.
THE BOTTOM LINE, IT IS HARD TO
THINK PAST THIS TRAGEDY.
WIN
WENDY, WHAT DO YOU SAY TO PEOPLE
TRYING TO GET PAST THIS?
>> WE HAVE TO UNDERSTAND THAT
NOT ONLY THOSE CHILDREN WHO
WITNESSED THINGS AND THE
FAMILIES WHO LOST CHILDREN WITH
ARE TRAUMATIZED BY THIS BUT
WE'RE ALL TRAUMATIZED BY THIS.
IT'S SORT OF SECONDARY
POSTTRAUMATIC STRESS DISORDER
THAT CAN OCCUR FROM WITNESSING
THE STORY OVER AND OVER ON
TELEVISION.
IT'S IMPORTANT WE CONTAIN
OURSELVES AND OUR EMOTIONS IN
FRONT OF OUR CHILDREN BUT STILL
SHOW COMPASSION AND LOVE.
LET THEM LEAD THE CONVERSATION
SO WE TELL THEM IN SIMPLE,
CONCRETE TERMS ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED.
WE ASSURE THEM THEY ARE
PROTECTED AND SAFE WITH US.
BUT MORE THAN ANYTHING, WE WATCH
FOR KIDS -- THEY HAVE VERY
DIFFERENT WAYS OF DEALING WITH
TRAUMA.
THEY MAY REGRESS.
YOUR CHILD MAY WANT WANT IN BED
WITH YOU AGAIN.
YOUR CHILD MAY WET THE BED AGAIN
LONG AFTER YOU THOUGHT IT WAS
DEALT WITH.
THIS IS NOT THE TIME TO BE
CRITICAL AND NOT OVER-PARENT BUT
UNDERSTAND THIS IS PART OF THE
PROCESS FOR SOME CHILDREN.
>> AND REVEREND SPENCER, WHEN WE
WERE GROWING UP, THE SCHOOLS,
OUR PLACES OF WORSHIP, THEY USED
TO BE SAFE HAVENS.
ONE PLACE EVIL NEVER STRUCK.
THAT HAS CHANGED.
HOW DO YOU TELL CHILDREN AND
PARENTS ON MONDAY THAT THEIR
SCHOOL IS SAFE?
>> WELL, I THINK MOST IMPORTANT
IS THAT WE REALLY BE HONEST WITH
YOUR CHILDREN AND WE TALK ABOUT
THE FACT THAT THERE IS AN EVIL
IN THE WORLD BUT THERE'S ALSO A
GOOD.
AND THEN CONTINUING TO REASSURE
THEM THAT THINGS WILL BE ALL
RIGHT AND THEN MAKE SURE THAT
WE'RE PUTTING THINGS IN PLACE TO
MAKE SURE THAT THEY KNOW THAT
THINGS WILL BE WELL.
CONSTANTLY REMINDING THEM THAT
WE'RE THERE FOR YOU AND WE'RE
SUPPORTING YOU.
LET THEM KNOW THE PEOPLE AT THE
SCHOOL OR AT CHURCH ARE THERE TO
SUPPORT YOU THROUGH THIS TIME.
>> AND AS WE LOOK AT THESE
PICTURES YOU'RE LOOKING AT, THIS
IS JUST DOWN THE SQUARE FROM
WHERE I'M STANDING.
THIS IS A MEMORIAL THAT HAS BEEN
SET UP.
THERE ARE 24 CANDLES THAT YOU
SEE THERE -- 26, I SHOULD SAY,
IN HONOR OF ALL OF THE VICTIMS
IN THIS TRAGEDY.
WENDY, AS WE LOOK AT THAT, WE
HAVE BEEN HEARING A LOT ABOUT
GUN CONTROL AND MENTAL HEALTH.
WHAT'S MORE IMPORTANT IN THIS
PARTICULAR ISSUE?
>> YOU KNOW, IT'S HARD TO SAY.
THE GUN CONTROL DEBATE HAS BEEN
GOING ON FOR SO LONG AND NOBODY
CAN FIGURE OUT WHERE AND HOW TO
DO THE REGULATION THAT THE
SECOND AMENDMENT MENTIONS.
YOU MENTIONED EARLIER WHEN YOU
READ IT, THE WORD WELL-REGULATED
IS IN THERE.
BUT WE DEFINITELY NEED SOME
MENTAL HEALTH REFORM.
UNFORTUNATELY IN AMERICA, YOU
ARE FREE TO BE INSANE, YOU ARE
FREE TO NOT TAKE YOUR MEDS.
YOU ARE FREE TO BE HOMELESS,
EVEN.
AND YOU ARE FREE TO KILL.
BUT WHEN ARE WE GOING TO PUT
COMPASSION ABOVE FREEDOM?
AND THAT MAY MEAN GIVING
FAMILIES AND DOCTORS MORE
AUTHORITY THAN WE HAVE BEEN ABLE
TO TO KEEP PEOPLE ON THEIR
MEDICATION, SO THAT THEY CAN
HAVE A BETTER WHEREWITHAL TO NOT
MAKE THESE CHOICES.
AND I THINK THAT THAT'S PART OF
IT IS THAT WE NEED TO UNDERSTAND
THAT WHEN AN EMERGING MENTAL
HEALTH PROBLEM -- THIS YOUNG MAN
WAS 20.
REMEMBER THE ARIZONA SHOOTER WAS
AROUND THE SAME AGE.
THIS TENDS TO BE A TIME THAT IF
YOU'RE GOING TO GET
SCHIZOPHRENIA AS A MALE, THE
SYMPTOMOLOGY SHOWS UP.
WE DON'T KNOW THIS GUY'S
DIAGNOSIS BUT I WANTED TO SAY
THAT.
IF YOU'RE OVER 18, YOUR PARENT
CAN'T EVEN GET YOU HELP BECAUSE
IT'S NOT THEIR RESPONSIBILITY
ANYMORE.
YOU'RE NOW A FREE ADULT.
>> WENDY, REVEREND SPENCER,
THANK YOU BOTH VERY MUCH.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> A LITTLE WHILE AGO, I TOOK A
WALK THROUGH THIS TOWN OF 27,000
PEOPLE.
ALL OF THEM STILL TRYING TO
PROCESS THE HORROR OF WHAT
HAPPENED JUST DOWN THE ROAD.
RIGHT BEHIND ME, THAT'S THE ROAD
THAT LEADS UP TO THE SCHOOL
WHERE THIS HAPPENED.
IT HAS BEEN BLOCKED OFF.
YOU CAN SEE THE SIGN HERE RIGHT
ACROSS THE STREET ON THAT PORCH,
IT SAYS, GOD BLESS SANDY HOOK.
AND RIGHT HERE IN THE MIDDLE OF
THE SQUARE, 26 CANDLES FOR ALL
OF THE VICTIMS IN THIS TRAGEDY
RIGHT HERE AT THE TIME SQUARE.
AND UP THE STREET, A CHURCH
WHERE THE VICTIMS ARE BEING
MEMORIALIZED.
THIS IS ONE OF THE INTIMATE
LITTLE SQUARES HERE IN SANDY
HOOK.
YOU CAN SEE THE LITTLE QUAINT
STORES, BEAUTIFUL LITTLE STORES.
AND THEN COME THIS WAY, YOU CAN
SEE JUST THE MEDIA.
AND PEOPLE HAVE TAKEN THIS
SQUARE OVER.
WHEN I TALK TO PEOPLE HERE, THEY
SAY, THERE'S NEVER THIS MANY
PEOPLE.
THERE ARE NEVER THIS MANY PEOPLE
WHO COME TO THIS TOWN ON A
SATURDAY OR SUNDAY.
TO SEE HOW INTIMATE AND
BEAUTIFUL THIS TOWN IS, LOOK, A
CREEK THAT RUNS RIGHT THROUGH
IT.
THE PEOPLE OF THIS SMALL TOWN
PROBABLY NEVER DREAMED THAT
THEIR TOWN WOULD BE TP FOCUS OF
SUCH PAIN AND ANGUISH AND
SORROW.
THIS IS THE NEWTOWN METHODIST
CHURCH.
THERE'S THE CHURCH BEHIND ME.
IT'S BEEN ONE