TAKE TO SAVE ANOTHER CHILD OR
ANOTHER PARENT OR ANOTHER TOWN
FROM THE GRIEF THAT'S VISITED
TUCSON AND AURORA AND OAK CREEK
AND NEWTOWN AND COMMUNITIES FROM
COLUMBINE TO BLACKSBURG BEFORE
THAT, THEN SURELY WE HAVE AN
OBLIGATION TO TRY.
IN THE COMING WEEKS, I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS,
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT, TO MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS, TO PARENTS
AND EDUCATORS, IN AN EFFORT
AIMED AT PREVENTING MORE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS, BECAUSE
WHAT CHOICE DO WE HAVE?
WE CAN'T ACCEPT EVENTS LIKE THIS
AS ROUTINE.
ARE WE REALLY PREPARED TO SAY
THAT WE'RE POWERLESS IN THE FACE
OF SUCH CARNAGE?
THAT THE POLITICS ARE TOO HARD.
ARE WE PREPARED TO SAY THAT SUCH
VIOLENCE VISITED ON OUR CHILDREN
YEAR AFTER YEAR AFTER YEAR IS
SOMEHOW THE PRICE OF OUR
FREEDOM?
YOU KNOW, ALL THE WORLD'S
RELIGIONS, SO MANY OF THEM
REPRESENTED HERE TODAY, START
WITH A SIMPLE QUESTION.
WHY ARE WE HERE?
WHAT GIVES OUR LIFE MEANING?
WHAT GIVES OUR ACTS PURPOSE?
WE KNOW OUR TIME ON THIS EARTH
IS FLEETING.
WE KNOW THAT WE WILL EACH HAVE
OUR SHARE OF PLEASURE AND PAIN,
THAT EVEN AFTER WE CHASE AFTER
SOME EARTHLY GOAL, WHETHER IT'S
WEALTH OR POWER OR FAME OR JUST
SIMPLE COMFORT, WE WILL, IN SOME
FASHION, FALL SHORT OF WHAT WE
HAD HOPED.
WE KNOW THAT NO MATTER HOW GOOD
OUR INTENTIONS, WE'LL ALL
STUMBLE SOMETIMES IN SOME WAY.
WE'LL MAKE MISTAKES, WE'LL
EXPERIENCE HARDSHIPS, AND EVEN
WHEN WE'RE TRYING TO DO THE
RIGHT THING, WE KNOW THAT MUCH
OF OUR TIME WILL BE SPENT
GROPING THROUGH THE DARKNESS, SO
OFTEN UNABLE TO DISCERN GOD'S
HEAVENLY PLANS.
THERE'S ONLY ONE THING WE CAN BE
SURE OF, AND THAT IS THE LOVE
THAT WE HAVE.
FOR OUR CHILDREN, FOR OUR
FAMILIES, FOR EACH OTHER.
THE WARMTH OF A SMALL CHILD'S
EMBRACE, THAT IS TRUE.
THE MEMORIES WE HAVE OF THEM,
THE JOY THAT THEY BRING, THE
WONDER WE SEE THROUGH THEIR
EYES, THAT FIERCE AND BOUNDLESS
LOVE WE FEEL FOR THEM, A LOVE
THAT TAKES US OUT OF OURSELVES
AND BINDS US TO SOMETHING
LARGER.
WE KNOW THAT'S WHAT MATTERS.
WE KNOW WE'RE ALWAYS DOING RIGHT
WHEN WE'RE TAKING CARE OF THEM.
WHEN WE'RE TEACHING THEM WELL.
WHEN WE'RE SHOWING ACTS OF
KINDNESS.
WE DON'T GO WRONG WHEN WE DO
THAT.
THAT'S WHAT WE CAN BE SURE OF,
AND THAT'S WHAT YOU, THE PEOPLE
OF NEWTOWN, HAVE REMINDED US.
THAT'S HOW YOU'VE INSPIRED US.
YOU REMIND US WHAT MATTERS.
AND THAT'S WHAT SHOULD DRIVE US
FORWARD IN EVERYTHING WE DO FOR
AS LONG AS GOD SEES FIT TO KEEP
US ON THIS EARTH.
LET THE LITTLE CHILDREN COME TO
ME, JESUS SAID, AND DO NOT
HINDER THEM, FOR TO SUCH BELONGS
THE KINGDOM OF HEAVEN.
CHARLOTTE, DANIEL, OLIVIA,
JOSEPHINE, ANA, DYLAN,
MADELEINE, CATHERINE, CHASE,
JESSE, JAMES, GRACE, EMILIE,
JACK, NOAH, CAROLINE, JESSICA,
BENJAMIN, AVIELLE, ALLISON.
GOD HAS CALLED THEM ALL HOME.
FOR THOSE OF US WHO REMAIN, LET
US FIND THE STRENGTH TO CARRY ON
AND MAKE OUR COUNTRY WORTHY OF
THEIR MEMORY.
MAY GOD BLESS AND KEEP THOSE
WE'VE LOST IN HIS HEAVENLY
PLACE.
MAY HE GRACE THOSE WE STILL HAVE
WITH HIS HOLY COMFORT, AND MAY
HE BLESS AND WATCH OVER THIS
COMMUNITY AND THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> ON BEHALF OF THE NEWTOWN
CLERGY ASSOCIATION, WE ARE SO
GRATEFUL TO OUR PRESIDENT FOR
SPENDING TIME WITH US AND FOR
REMINDING US THAT WE ARE NOT
ALONE IN THIS TIME OF TRAGEDY,
THAT THERE'S NOT JUST A COUNTRY
STANDING BEHIND US, THAT THERE'S
A WORLD STANDING BEHIND US.
THOSE WORDS I KNOW AS DIFFICULT
AS THEY WERE TO HEAR FOR SOME,
BROUGHT MUCH CONSOLATION TO ALL.
I WANT TO THANK OUR GOVERNOR AND
ALL THE STATE OFFICIALS WHO HAVE
BEEN BY OUR SIDE SINCE DAY ONE.
THEY HAVE BEEN A REMARKABLE
REMINDER TO US OF THEIR HUMANITY
AND THEIR CARE FOR US.
BUT MOST OF ALL, I WANT TO THANK
AN INCREDIBLE FIRST-SELECT WOMAN
WHO'S LED US THROUGH THE MOST
DARK PERIODS OF OUR LIVES.
IN THE STORMS OF THE PAST YEARS
RAVAGED OUR COMMUNITY WITHOUT
POWER FOR DAYS, I THOUGHT THOSE
WERE THE HARDEST DAYS OF PAT'S
LIFE, BUT WHEN I SAW HER FRIDAY
IN FRONT OF SANDY HOOK SCHOOL, I
REALIZED THAT SHE'D MET THE MOST
DARK DAYS.
PAT, TO YOU, TO DR. ROBINSON, WE
THANK YOU FOR BEING LEADERS TO
US THROUGH THESE DIFFICULT
TIMES.
AND NOW THIS FINAL PART OF OUR
PRAYER IS FOR US, THE PEOPLE OF
NEWTOWN.
>> THESE ARE THE WORDS OF THE
APOSTLE PAUL AS HE WRITES TO THE
CHURCH AT ROME.
WHAT THEN SHALL WE SAY IN
RESPONSE TO THIS, IF GOD IS FOR
US, WHO CAN BE AGAINST US?
HE WHO DID NOT SPARE HIS OWN
SON, BUT GAVE HIM UP FOR ALL OF
US, HOW WILL HE NOT ALSO ALONG
WITH HIM GRACIOUSLY GIVE US ALL
THINGS?
WHO WILL BRING ANY CHARGE
AGAINST THOSE WHOM GOD HAS
CHOSEN, THAT IS GOD WHO
JUSTIFIES, WHO IS HE THAT
CONDEMNS?
CHRIST JESUS WHO DIED, MORE THAN
THAT WHO WAS RAISED TO LIFE, WAS
AT THE RIGHT HAND OF GOD AND IS
ALSO INTERCEDING FOR US.
WHO SHALL SEPARATE US FROM THE
LOVE OF CHRIST, SHALL TROUBLE OR
HARDSHIP OR PERSECUTION OR
FAMINE OR NAKEDNESS OR DANGER OR
SWORD AS IT IS WRITTEN FOR YOUR
SAKE, WE FACE DEATH ALL DAY
LONG, WE ARE CONSIDERED AS SHEEP
TO BE SLAUGHTERED.
KNOW IN ALL THESE THINGS WE ARE
MORE THAN CONQUERERS THROUGH HIM
WHO LOVED US, FOR I AM CONVINCED
THAT NEITHER DEATH, NOR LIFE,
NEITHER ANGELS, NOR DEMONS,
NEITHER THE PRESENCE, NOR THE
FUTURE, NEITHER ANY POWERS,
HEIGHT, NOR DEPTH, IN ALL
CREATION WILL BE ABLE TO
SEPARATE US FROM THE LOVE OF GOD
THAT IS IN CHRIST JESUS OUR
LORD.
>> AND SO WE STAND NOW IN PRAYER
FOR OURSELVES.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN, BUT OUR
SPIRITS ARE STRENGTHENED BY THE
POWER OF GOD'S GOODNESS AND HIS
EVER-CREATING LOVE AND BY THE
GENEROUS HEARTS OF A COMMUNITY
WHO TRULY CARES.
WE HAVE SHOWN TO THE WORLD OUR
COMPASSION.
BUT YOU HAVE PLACED ON OUR
SHOULDERS A BURDEN OF IMAGINABLE
PAIN.
YOU HAVE PUT IN OUR HEARTS THE
RESOLVE TO WORK TOGETHER TO MAKE
OF THIS WORLD A PLACE OF
JUSTICE, OF PEACE, OF TRUTH, FOR
OUR PEOPLE, ESPECIALLY FOR OUR
YOUNG.
WE THANK YOU THIS NIGHT FOR OUR
COMMUNITY LEADERS WHO HAVE
WALKED A DARK ROAD HELPING US
FIND A LIGHT.
WE PRAY FOR MEN AND FOR WOMEN
AND WHOSE LOVE FOR EACH OTHER
HAS GIVEN US CHILDREN THAT WE
MIGHT GUIDE AND ENCOURAGE THEM.
WE SEEK YOUR WISDOM AS OUR
ADMINISTRATORS AND OUR EDUCATORS
CONTINUE TO TEACH OUR CHILDREN
WAYS TO STRENGTHEN THEM TO BE
PRODUCTIVE AND POSITIVE CITIZENS
OF THIS WORLD, TO ONLY BRING
RIGHT AND GOOD, NOT HARM OR
HURT.
WE PRAY THAT THIS CULTURE OF
DEATH THAT IS OVERSHADOWING OUR
ENTIRE COUNTRY, ESPECIALLY NOW
IN THIS, OUR TOWN, WILL SOON BE
REPLACED WITH A CULTURE OF LIFE
THAT EMBRACES EVERY PERSON WITH
HUMAN DIGNITY.
WE ARE BROUGHT TO YOU TONIGHT IN
OUR PRAYER THOSE WE HAVE LOST,
THOSE WHOSE HEARTS HAVE BEEN
BROKEN FOREVER.
WE BRING TO YOU 20 NEW STARS IN
THE HEAVENS, 20 NEW SAINTS, 20
NEW ANGELS.
WE BRING TO YOU THOSE WHO RISKED
THEIR LIVES FOR US EVERY DAY,
NOT COUNTING THE COST.
AND WE BRING TO YOU THOSE WHO
GUIDE, THOSE WHO COUNSEL, THOSE
WHO BLESS AND EMBRACE THE
CONFUSED AND THE BROKEN.
AND NOW IN THIS PRAYER WE BRING
TO YOU OURSELVES, OUR
BROKENNESS, OUR QUESTIONS, OUR
DOUBTS, OUR ANGER, AND OUR
HEARTS.
AND WE PRAY FOR THE PEACE, THE
HOPE, AND THE RENEWAL OF TRUST
THAT CAN COME ONLY FROM A GOD
WHO FIRST CONCEIVED US IN LOVE
AND PLACED A HAND OF COMPASSION
ON EACH OF OUR SHOULDERS, EVEN
IN THIS MOST CHALLENGING TIME.
AND SO TONIGHT, FOR OUR
COMMUNITY, A COMMUNITY DEEPLY
PAINED, WE ASK YOU TO HEAL THE
BROKENNESS, TO ANSWER OUR
QUESTIONS, TO REPLACE OUR DOUBTS
WITH CERTAINTY, OUR ANGER WITH
PEACE, AND OUR HURT WITH
HEALING.
GOD, WE THANK YOU FOR THIS TOWN.
WE THANK YOU FOR ITS PEOPLE.
AND WE THANK YOU FOR THIS
OPPORTUNITY TO STAND TOGETHER
AND NOT TO FALL APART.
AMEN.
>> NOW A FINAL BLESSING OF HOPE
THROUGH FAITH IN JESUS CHRIST
FROM THE WORDS OF ST. JOHN AND
SAINT PAUL.
I HEARD A LOUD VOICE FROM THE
THRONE SAYING, BEHOLD THE
DWELLING PLACE OF GOD IS WITH
MAN.
HE WILL DWELL WITH THEM AND THEY
WILL BE HIS PEOPLE AND GOD
HIMSELF WILL BE WITH THEM AS
THEIR GOD.
HE WILL WIPE AWAY EVERY TEAR
FROM THEIR EYES AND DEATH SHALL
BE NO MORE.
NEITHER SHALL THERE BE MOURNING,
NOR CRYING, NOR PAIN ANYMORE,
FOR THE FORMER THINGS HAVE
PASSED AWAY, AND HE WHO WAS
SEATED ON THE THRONE SAID,
BEHOLD I AM MAKING ALL THINGS
NEW.
AND NOW, MAY THE GRACE OF OUR
LORD JESUS CHRIST AND THE LOVE
OF GOD AND THE COMMUNION OF THE
HOLY SPIRIT BE WITH YOU ALL.
AMEN.
I ASK YOU TO PLEASE TAKE YOUR
SEATS UNTIL I CAN RECEIVE
CONFIRMATION THAT THE PRESIDENT
HAS SAFELY EXITED THE SCHOOL
CAMPUS.
AND I DON'T KNOW WHO THAT
CONFIRMATION IS GOING TO COME
FROM.
BUT ALLOW ME TO SAY WHILE I WAIT
FOR THAT, WE THEN ENCOURAGE ALL
OF YOU, ON BEHALF OF THE NEWTOWN
CLERGY, GIVE TO ONE ANOTHER ALL
THE LOVE AND CARE AND SUPPORT
THAT YOU CAN.
AND CLERGY WILL BE AVAILABLE FOR
YOU AT THIS TIME AT THE PLATFORM
FOR A TIME OF PRAYER, ACCORDING
TO EACH OF THEIR TEACHINGS AND
BELIEFS.
SO PLEASE DO REMAIN SEATED UNTIL
I RECEIVE THAT WORD OF
CONFIRMATION AND THEN COMFORT
ONE ANOTHER.
>> A POWERFUL, VERY MOVING
INTERFAITH PRAYER VIGIL HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE HEARD FROM THE CLERGY, FROM
VARIOUS RELIGIONS, RELIGIONS OF
THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA.
WE HEARD, OF COURSE, FROM THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES,
AND HE VOWED AFTER THE SENSELESS
MURDERS IN ARIZONA, IN COLORADO,
IN WISCONSIN, AND NOW HERE IN
CONNECTICUT, HE VOWED THAT HE
WOULD DO WHATEVER HIS OFFICE
WOULD ALLOW HIM TO DO, WHATEVER
POWERS HE NOW HAS, TO TRY TO
MAKE SURE THIS DOES NOT HAPPEN
AGAIN.
AND HE WILL WORK DILIGENTLY IN
THAT AREA.
ANDERSON COOPER, WE WATCHED
THESE FAITHS, THEY WERE WELL
REPRESENTATIVE.
WE CAN ONLY HOPE AND PRAY THAT
THOSE WHO NOW MOURN WILL GET AT
LEAST A LITTLE BIT OF COMFORT
FROM WHAT WE JUST SAW.
>> AND THE PRESIDENT TOWARD THE
END OF HIS REMARKS ASKING IF WE
ARE, ALL OF US AS A SOCIETY,
DOING ALL WE CAN TO PROTECT OUR
CHILDREN.
HE SAID HE FELT WE ARE NOT AND
HE SAID WE CAN DO BETTER.
VERY POWERFUL WORDS FROM
PRESIDENT OBAMA ENDING THIS
CEREMONY, AND NOW PEOPLE IN THE
AUDIENCE GREETING ONE ANOTHER,
HUGGING ONE ANOTHER.
FIRST RESPONDERS ARE STILL
INSIDE.
WOLF, VERY MOVING MOMENT WHEN
THE FIRST RESPONDERS CAME INTO
THE ROOM SHORTLY BEFORE THE
SERVICE BEGAN, THERE WAS A
STANDING OVATION FOR THEM.
NO DOUBT MANY PEOPLE NOW
APPROACHING THOSE FIRST
RESPONDERS, JUST WANTING TO
THANK THEM, SHAKE THEIR HAND,
HUG THEM, PERHAPS SHARE A TEAR
WITH THEM.
A LOT OF PEOPLE WHO WERE
WATCHING IN OVERFLOW ROOMS AND
OUTSIDE HUDDLED UNDER BLANKETS
GIVEN BY THE RED CROSS ARE
SLOWLY WALKING AWAY, PAST THE
LOCATION WHERE WE ARE, PAST A
MAKESHIFT MEMORIAL, WHICH IS
OUTSIDE THE HIGH SCHOOL, PAUSING
FOR A MOMENT.
SOME CARRYING CANDLES.
SOME DEPOSITING THOSE CANDLES
DOWN ON THE GROUND, SLOWLY
WALKING BACK TO THEIR CARS WITH
THEIR FAMILIES.
THIS HAS BEEN A VERY MOVING
SERVICE HEARING FROM, AS YOU
SAID, A NUMBER OF DENOMINATIONS,
FROM PASTORS, WE HEARD FROM A
RABBI, AS WELL AS A
REPRESENTATIVE OF THE MUSLIM
COMMUNITY, SINGING.
OVERALL, VERY MOVING CEREMONY.
DON LEMON IS STANDING BY.
HE'S BEEN TALKING WITH PEOPLE
WHO HAVE BEEN WATCHING THE
SERVICE, WHO HAVE BEEN STOPPING
BY THE MAKESHIFT MEMORIAL ALL
EVENING LONG.
DON, WHAT HAVE YOU BEEN HEARING
FROM PEOPLE?
>> Reporter: I'VE BEEN HEARING A
LOT.
PEOPLE, OF COURSE, COMING BY TO
LIGHT CANDLES AND DROP THINGS
OFF, ANDERSON.
SOME WERE STANDING OUT HERE
WATCHING THE MEMORIAL ON THEIR
SMARTPHONES ON CNN AND THE STONE
RIVER GRILL, A TAVERN ACROSS THE
STREET THEY WERE WATCHING.
YOU CAN SEE THERE'S A BAND HERE
THAT SAYS, "REMEMBER THE
CHILDREN."
THEY WALKED BY.
THEY HAD BEEN PLAYING AND
WALKING UP AND DOWN THE STREET
HERE.
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN HUGGING EACH
OTHER.
THEY HAVE BEEN CRYING, THEY HAVE
BEEN COMFORTING EACH OTHER.
THE PEOPLE WHO ARE WATCHING IN
THE TAVERN ACROSS THE STREET
AFTER THE PRESIDENT SPOKE CAME
OUT TO TALK.
SOME PEOPLE WERE WATCHING IN
RESTAURANTS.
CHRIS, YOU WERE WATCHING AS
WELL.
THE PRESIDENT OFFER ANY WORDS OF
COMFORT TO YOU?
>> YEAH, I THINK HE -- WHAT HE
SAID THAT WAS COMFORTING IS IT'S
TIME FOR CHANGE AND TIME TO
ACTUALLY DO SOMETHING ABOUT ALL
THE VIOLENCE WE'VE BEEN HAVING
LATELY IN THIS COUNTRY.
>> Reporter: AND YOU KNOW THAT
VIOLENCE.
>> YEAH, I HAD A SON THAT WAS
MURDERED FIVE AND A HALF YEARS
AGO, SO THIS DEFINITELY STIRS UP
A LOT OF THOSE EMOTIONS FOR ME,
ABSOLUTELY, WITH ALL THE LITTLE
INNOCENT CHILDREN THAT DIED.
>> Reporter: TO SEE THIS
MEMORIAL AND TO SEE THE PEOPLE
ALL COMING TOGETHER, DOES THAT
COMFORT YOU AT ALL TO THE PEOPLE
IN THE COMMUNITY?
>> IT DOES.
IT'S A WONDERFUL AREA.
PEOPLE IN NEWTOWN ARE BEAUTIFUL
PEOPLE.
I THINK IT'S -- I THINK THE WAY
PEOPLE ARE JUST BONDING
TOGETHER, IT SAYS A LOT ABOUT
THIS COMMUNITY, JUST THIS PART
OF THE COUNTRY.
>> Reporter: THANK YOU.
THERE ARE PEOPLE HERE THAT ARE
HANGING JAPANESE BIRDS OVER HERE
THAT THEY SAID THAT THEY'D HAD
DURING THEIR WEDDING.
1,000 WISHES, THEY SAY, FOR
EVERYONE INVOLVED IN THIS.
OTHER FOLKS COMING REALLY FROM
ALL AROUND THE AREA JUST TO PAY
THEIR RESPECTS AND TO OFFER
COMFORT TO EACH OTHER HERE AS WE
LISTEN TO THIS BAND AND WE
FINISH UP THE MEMORIAL HERE.
THIS ONE IS TEMPORARY, BUT I'M
SURE A PERMANENT ONE WILL BE
ERECTED, BUT THIS ONE WILL HAVE
TO OFFER COMFORT FOR THE TIME
BEING.
WOLF BLITZER, MOVING CEREMONY BY
THE PRESIDENT, VERY TOUCHING
MOMENT REALLY HERE IN NEWTOWN IN
THE SQUARE WHERE PEOPLE ARE JUST
PAYING THEIR RESPECTS AND LOVING
EACH OTHER.
>> AS THEY SHOULD RIGHT NOW.
I THINK THE WHOLE COUNTRY HAS
BEEN MOVED BY WHAT WE HAVE JUST
SEEN AND WILL REFLECT ON WHAT WE
HAVE JUST SEEN AS WELL.
I WAS ESPECIALLY MOVED AT THE
END WHEN THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES READ THE NAMES OF
THOSE KIDS WHO WERE KILLED
FRIDAY MORNING AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
AND LET'S REMEMBER WHO THESE
PEOPLE WERE.
♪
>> JUST A TRAGIC, TRAGIC
SITUATION FOR THE TEACHERS, THE
PRINCIPALS, AND THOSE ANGELS.
THAT'S ALL I KEEP THINKING ABOUT
IS THOSE ANGELS.
♪
>> I MEAN, WHEN THINGS HAPPEN TO
YOUR CHILDREN, AND TO OTHER
PEOPLE'S CHILDREN, I CAN'T LOOK
AT MY CHILDREN'S FACES NOW
WITHOUT SEEING THE FACES OF
EVERY ONE OF THEIR SCHOOLMATES.
♪
>>> GOOD EVENING, IT'S BEEN AN
INCREDIBLY MOVING VIGIL TONIGHT
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, AS THE
COMMUNITY COMES TOGETHER TO
MOURN ITS LOST CHILDREN AND
TEACHERS.
THIS COUNTRY IS GRIEVING AS
WELL.
VISIBLY EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT
OBAMA MET WITH FAMILIES,
INCLUDING THE BABY GRANDDAUGHTER
OF SLAIN PRINCIPAL DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG, THEN HE SPOKE TO THE
PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN AND THE
NATION, PROMISING TO DO ALL HE
CAN TO PREVENT FURTHER TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS.
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS, I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS,
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT, TO MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS, TO PARENTS
AND EDUCATORS, IN AN EFFORT
AIMED AT PREVENTING MORE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS, BECAUSE
WHAT CHOICE DO WE HAVE?
WE CAN'T ACCEPT EVENTS LIKE THIS
AS ROUTINE.
ARE WE REALLY PREPARED TO SAY
THAT WE'RE POWERLESS IN THE FACE
OF SUCH CARNAGE?
>> IN THE MIDST OF HIS ALMOST
INCOMPREHENSIBLE TRAGEDY, THERE
WERE HEROS, ONE OF THEM, VICKI
SOTO, A 27-YEAR-OLD TEACHER,
GAVE HER LIFE TO PROTECT HER
STUDENTS.
JOINING ME NOW, VICKI'S SISTER,
MOTHER, BROTHER, COUSIN, WELCOME
TO YOU ALL.
IT'S BEEN AN INCREDIBLY MOVING
DAY, AGAIN, IN NEWTOWN.
AND THE WORDS OF THE PRESIDENT
IN PARTICULAR THIS EVENING, VERY
CONTROLLED ANGER, HE WANTS TO
TRY TO DO SOMETHING, ANYTHING,
TO STOP THIS HAPPENING AGAIN.
THE APPALLING TRAGEDY, WHICH HAS
EFFECTED SO MANY FAMILIES,
INCLUDING YOUR OWN.
IF I MAY START WITH YOU, DONNA,
VICKI WAS YOUR DAUGHTER, SHE WAS
27.
THERE HAVE BEEN SO MANY TRIBUTES
TO HER PAID BY SO MANY PEOPLE.
WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE TO SAY?
>> I'D JUST LIKE EVERYONE TO
KNOW THAT SHE WAS JUST A
BEAUTIFUL, BEAUTIFUL YOUNG LADY.
SHE HAD SUCH PASSION FOR
TEACHING AND FOR LIFE AND
ESPECIALLY FOR HER FAMILY.
SHE WAS EXTREMELY CLOSE TO HER
SIBLINGS THAT ARE SITTING WITH
ME, HER COUSINS, AND LOVED THEM
DEARLY.
AND WANTED TO BE A TEACHER FROM
THE TIME SHE WAS 3.
THAT'S ALL SHE EVER WANTED TO
DO.
SHE JUST LOVED HER KIDS.
SHE JUST TALKED ABOUT THEM ALL
THE TIME WITH SUCH FONDNESS AND
CARING, AND SHE JUST ADORED
THEM.
AND I HAVE NO DOUBT IN MY MIND
SHE DID EVERYTHING SHE COULD TO
PROTECT EVERY SINGLE ONE OF
THEM.
>> WHAT SHE DID WAS INCREDIBLY
HEROIC, AND SHE SAVED MANY LIVES
WITH HER ACTIONS.
KNOWING HER, AS HER MOTHER, AS
WELL AS ANYBODY IN THE WORLD
KNEW HER, DID IT SURPRISE YOU
THAT SHE WAS SO COURAGEOUS IN
SUCH A TERRIFYING MOMENT?
>> NOT AT ALL.
SHE WAS TRULY SELFLESS.
SHE WOULD NOT HESITATE TO THINK
TO SAVE ANYONE ELSE BEFORE
HERSELF, AND ESPECIALLY
CHILDREN.
SHE LOVED THEM MORE THAN LIFE,
AND SHE WOULD DEFINITELY PUT
HERSELF IN FRONT OF THEM ANY
DAY, ANY DAY AND FOR ANY REASON.
IT DOESN'T SURPRISE ANYBODY THAT
KNOWS VICKI THAT SHE DID THIS.
>> CARLY, VICKI WAS YOUR SISTER,
YOU WERE ALL VERY CLOSE, AS YOUR
MOTHER JUST SAID.
IT'S OBVIOUSLY A TERRIBLE,
TORRENTIAL LOSS, YOU MUST BE
GRIEVING HORRIBLY, YET AT THE
SAME TIME HEARING THE PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED STATES TALK ABOUT
YOUR SISTER AS A HERO, IT MUST
HAVE BEEN VERY MOVING TO YOU.
>> IT WAS VERY MUCH.
I APPRECIATE ALL HIS KIND WORDS
THAT HE DID SAY ABOUT MY SISTER.
SHE WAS A HERO, AND SHE STILL
IS.
>> WHAT KIND OF PERSON WAS SHE,
CARLEE?
>> SHE WAS SO CARING.
SHE PUT ANYBODY ELSE BEFORE HER.
SHE WANTED THE BEST FOR
EVERYONE.
SHE JUST LOVED LIFE, AND SHE
LOVED TEACHING.
>> AND JILLIAN, YOU'RE ALL
WEARING GREEN BECAUSE THAT WAS
VICKI'S FAVORITE COLOR, AND I
HEARD YOU SAY THIS MORNING THAT
WHEN IT SNOWED, YOU FELT IT WAS
IN SOME WAY A SIGNAL FROM YOUR
SISTER.
>> IT WAS.
IT'S LIKE HER LOOKING DOWN AT US
AND LETTING US KNOW THAT SHE'S
HERE WITH US AND SHE LOVED THE
CHRISTMAS HOLIDAY.
SHE LOVED EVERYTHING ABOUT IT,
THE SNOW THAT COMES WITH IT, SO
WHEN IT STARTED TO HAIL, THE
THREE OF US KNEW IT WAS OUR
SISTER SAYING THAT I'M HERE WITH
YOU GUYS, EVEN THROUGH ALL OF
THIS.
GREEN IS HER FAVORITE COLOR.
>> I'M SORRY.
>> WE JUST WANTED TO WEAR THE
GREEN TO SHOW HOW MUCH WE LOVE
HER AND HONOR HER FOR IT.
>> CARLOS, YOU WERE VICKI'S
BROTHER.
WHEN YOU HEARD WHAT HAD HAPPENED
AT THE SCHOOL, IT MUST HAVE
BEEN, I IMAGINE, THE WORST
MOMENT OF YOUR LIFE.
TRY AND SUM UP FOR ME WHAT IT'S
BEEN LIKE FOR YOU AS A FAMILY
SINCE THIS DREADFUL, DREADFUL
MOMENT HAPPENED.
>> IT'S JUST BEEN HORRIBLE.
THERE'S BEEN SO MANY PEOPLE HERE
TO SUPPORT US, AND I REALLY
THINK THAT SHE WANTED US TO COME
BACK TOGETHER.
AND WE'VE ALWAYS BEEN CLOSE, BUT
SHE'S JUST GOING TO BRING US
CLOSER, AND I KNOW WE'LL ALWAYS
REMEMBER HER FOR THIS.
>> AND CARLOS, HOW DO YOU FEEL
ABOUT THE WAY THE COMMUNITY HAS
RALLIED TOGETHER?
THE PRESIDENT NOTICED THIS,
YOU'VE COME TOGETHER AS A
COMMUNITY, NOT JUST THOSE WHO
HAVE LOST PEOPLE, BUT JUST THE
WHOLE COMMUNITY.
AND YOU'VE BEEN JOINED BY
AMERICA, I THINK, THAT'S BEEN
SHATTERED BY WHAT'S HAPPENED,
FROM THE PRESIDENT DOWN.
WHAT DO YOU THINK WILL HAPPEN
WITH NEWTOWN NOW?
HOW WILL THEY RECOVER FROM THIS?
>> I DON'T THINK IT WILL EVER BE
A FULL RECOVERY.
I KNOW THAT THESE 27 PEOPLE THAT
LOST THEIR LIVES WILL BE
REMEMBERED AND WILL BE MISSED TO
THE FULLEST, AND I JUST -- IT'S
JUST SO THANKFUL TO KNOW THAT
EVERYONE IN STRATFORD HAS BEEN
TOUCHED BY HER LIFE SOMEHOW AND
CAME HERE TO CELEBRATE HER LIFE.
>> I UNDERSTAND, DONNA, THAT YOU
AND CARLEE MET WITH THE
PRESIDENT TODAY.
CAN YOU TALK ABOUT THAT?
>> WE ALL MET WITH THE PRESIDENT
TODAY.
IT WAS -- HE WAS VERY, VERY
CARING AND VERY SUPPORTIVE AND
TOLD US HE KNEW ALL ABOUT VICKI
AND WHAT SHE DID AND WHAT A HERO
SHE WAS.
AND SHE WAS JUST VERY, VERY KIND
TO US AND GAVE US THE TIME WE
NEEDED WITH HIM, AND IT WAS --
IT WAS VERY COMFORTING.
>> AND JAMES, YOU WERE VICKI'S
COUSIN, YOU'RE ALSO A POLICE
OFFICER.
IT WAS VERY NOTICEABLE IN THE
PRESIDENT'S SPEECH TONIGHT THAT
HE SEEMS, ALTHOUGH HE NEVER
MENTIONED THE WORD GUNS, HE'S
DETERMINED TO DO WHATEVER HE
CAN, HE SAID, TO TRY AND PREVENT
ANOTHER SHOOTING TRAGEDY LIKE
THIS.
AND MANY ARE TAKING THIS TO MEAN
GUN CONTROL, WHATEVER IT MAY BE.
WHAT WAS YOUR REACTION AS A
POLICEMAN TO WHAT HE WAS SAYING
THERE?
>> I GOT TO BE HONEST, I DIDN'T
SEE OR HEAR HIS SPEECH YET.
WE -- AFTER WE MET WITH HIM, HE
WAS JUST LOVE AND SUPPORT FROM
HIM WAS COMFORTING FOR THE
FAMILY.
I GOT THE FAMILY BACK HERE TO
STRATFORD.
TO TRY AND ANSWER YOUR QUESTION,
JUST AS ANY OTHER ISSUE, I WOULD
HAVE TO SAY AWARENESS,
AWARENESS, AWARENESS.
FRIENDS, FAMILY, GUN SUPPORTERS,
PEOPLE THAT OPPOSE GUNS, JUST
AWARENESS.
AND BEING AWARE OF YOUR
SURROUNDINGS.
>> I WANT TO THANK YOU ALL
FOR --
>> I DON'T KNOW WHAT ELSE TO
SAY.
>> LISTEN, I DON'T WANT TO PRESS
YOU ON THIS.
IT'S NOT THE TIME FOR YOU AS A
FAMILY TO CONSIDER THESE THINGS.
IT WILL BE FOR THE PRESIDENT AND
POLITICIANS, I THINK, TO DO WHAT
NEEDS TO BE DONE.
THANK YOU ALL VERY MUCH FOR
TAKING THE TIME TO JOIN ME THIS
EVENING AND JUST TO SEND YOU ON
BEHALF OF EVERYONE AT CNN AND
AMERICA THAT'S BEEN THINKING OF
YOU AND YOUR FAMILY.
VICKI WAS A HEROINE, TRUE
AMERICAN, YOUR LOSS IS APPALLING
BUT HER LEGACY AND MEMORY WILL
LIVE ON FOR A VERY, VERY LONG
TIME.
THANK YOU ALL VERY MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
>> BRAVE FAMILY.
I WANT TO BRING YOU WOLF
BLITZER, WHO'S ON THE SCENE OF
TONIGHT'S VIGIL.
WOLF, IT'S A PRETTY UNBEARABLE
STORY, THIS, TO COVER.
YOU CAN ONLY BEGIN TO IMAGINE
WHAT ON EARTH THESE FAMILIES ARE
GOING THROUGH.
WHAT DID YOU MAKE OF THE
PRESIDENT'S SPEECH TONIGHT?
VERY EMOTIONAL, PRETTY
DETERMINED, AND ALTHOUGH HE
DIDN'T MENTION THE WORD GUNS,
PRETTY OBVIOUS, I THINK, HE'S
GOING TO TRY TO DO SOMETHING
FAIRLY DRAMATIC TO TRY AND DO
SOMETHING, AS HE PUT IT, DOING
NOTHING IS NOT AN OPTION
ANYMORE.
>> Reporter: HE SAYS HE'S GOING
TO USE EVERY OPPORTUNITY HE HAS
WITH THE POWER OF HIS OFFICE,
THE PRESIDENCY OF THE UNITED
STATES, TO TRY TO MAKE SURE THIS
DOES NOT HAPPEN AGAIN.
EVEN IF HE CAN SAVE ONE OR TWO
OR THREE YOUNG KIDS, HE WANTS TO
DO IT.
AND IT WAS A CLEAR REFERENCE, I
DON'T THINK THERE'S ANY DOUBT,
PIERS, WHAT THE PRESIDENT WAS
TALKING ABOUT, EVEN THOUGH HE
DIDN'T SAY, FOR EXAMPLE, WE
MUST, YOU KNOW, GET NEW GUN
LEGISLATION TO CONTROL GUNS IN
THE UNITED STATES, THE ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN OR WHATEVER, THAT'S
CLEARLY WHAT HE'S DRIVING AT AND
WHAT HE'S GOING TO TRY TO DO.
WHETHER OR NOT HE SUCCEEDS IS
ANOTHER MANNER.
AS YOU KNOW, THERE'S A LOT OF
OPPOSITION TO A MUCH GREATER GUN
CONTROL IN THIS COUNTRY, BUT I
THINK HE'S GOING TO TRY.
HE DIDN'T TRY DURING THE FIRST
FOUR YEARS.
THERE WERE A LOT OF OTHER ISSUES
ON HIS AGENDA, INCLUDING A U.S.
ECONOMY THAT WAS NEAR, NOT ONLY
RECESSION, BUT POTENTIALLY
ANOTHER DEPRESSION.
A LOT GOING ON, TWO WARS.
BUT RIGHT NOW, HAVING JUST BEEN
REELECTED, HAVING JUST GONE
THROUGH WHAT WE HEARD ONE OF THE
MINISTERS SAY, ONE OF THE PEOPLE
WHO MET WITH HIM, THIS PAST
FRIDAY WHEN HE HEARD ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED AT THAT ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, THE WORST DAY OF
HIS PRESIDENCY, I THINK THERE'S
NO DOUBT HE'S GOING TO TRY TO DO
SOMETHING IN THIS SECOND TERM AS
FAR AS GUN CONTROL IS CONCERNED.
THAT WILL BE A PRIORITY.
HE WANTS TO USE THE OFFICE OF
THE PRESIDENCY TO TRY TO SAVE
SOME LIVES, AND I THINK HE'S
GOING TO DO THE BEST HE CAN ON
THIS AREA.
I DON'T KNOW IF HE'LL SUCCEED,
BECAUSE THIS IS A TOUGH ISSUE,
AS YOU KNOW, IN THE U.S. SENATE,
U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,
BUT HE'LL GIVE IT A SHOT.
>> I THINK THAT'S RIGHT.
AND I THINK HE'S PICKED UP ON
WHAT'S A NATIONAL MOOD THAT I
DETECT AFTER THIS PARTICULAR
HORRIFYING INCIDENT, ONE OF THE
WORST YOU COULD POSSIBLY
IMAGINE.
I DETECT THERE'S A DIFFERENT
MOOD ABOUT THIS ISSUE AND ACTION
HAS TO BE TAKEN.
THE AMERICAN PUBLIC ARE GOING TO
DEMAND IT.
WOLF, FOR NOW, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH INDEED.
>>> THE TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN
RAISES DIFFICULT AND PAINFUL
QUESTIONS, QUESTIONS PEOPLE
ACROSS THE COUNTRY ARE ALL
WRESTLING WITH TONIGHT.
WHEN WE COME BACK, XAVIER
AMADOR, A CONSULTANT ON MANY
MASS SHOOTINGS.
WHAT HE NOW THINKS.
THIS IS AMERICA.
WE DON'T LET FREQUENT HEARTBURN
COME BETWEEN US
AND WHAT WE LOVE.
SO IF YOU'RE ONE OF THEM PEOPLE
WHO GETS HEARTBURN
AND THEN TREATS DAY AFTER DAY...
BLOCK THE ACID WITH PRILOSEC OTC
AND DON'T GET HEARTBURN
IN THE FIRST PLACE!
[ Male Announcer ]
ONE PILL EACH MORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBURN.
>>> WITH CANDLES, FLOWERS, AND
CARDS, PEOPLE GATHERED TONIGHT
AT A MEMORIAL FOR THE VICTIMS IN
NEWTOWN.
WE'RE LEARNING MORE DETAILS
ABOUT THE GUNMAN, ADAM LANZA.
JOINING ME IS AMADOR, HE'S
CONSULTED ON MANY MASS SHOOTINGS
IN THE PAST.
WE SPOKE ON FRIDAY.
RIGHT AT THE TOP, I WANT TO TALK
ABOUT SOMETHING WE DISCUSSED,
WHICH IS ABOUT THE POTENTIAL
MENTAL ILLNESS THAT THIS YOUNG
MAN SUFFERED FROM.
IT'S SUGGESTED THAT IT IS
POSSIBLY ASPERGERS, A FORM OF
AUTISM.
CLARIFY THAT AND CLARIFY WHETHER
THERE'S ANY REAL SCIENCE THAT
SUGGEST PEOPLE THAT HAVE THAT
KIND OF CONDITION MIGHT BE
VIOLENT.
>> THERE IS NONE.
THERE'S ABSOLUTELY NO EVIDENCE
THAT IF YOU HAVE ASPERGER'S,
YOU'RE MORE LIKELY TO BE VIOLENT
THAN ANYBODY ELSE.
I GOT SOME E-MAILS AND BLOGS
AFTER OUR LAST CONVERSATION.
I DIDN'T INTEND TO SAY PEOPLE
WITH ASPERGER'S LACK EMPATHY,
THEY LACK THE ABILITY TO JUDGE
SOCIAL CUES.
I LOOK AT YOU LIKE YOU'RE
LOOKING AT ME, IT MAY LOOK LIKE
I DON'T HAVE EMPATHY, I WANTED
TO CLARIFY THAT AS WELL.
>> MORE AND MORE DETAIL
EMERGING, NO SIGN OF MOTIVE.
KILLED HIS MOTHER, WENT TO THE
SCHOOL AND CLEARLY LOOKS LIKE HE
PLANNED IT QUITE CAREFULLY.
THE FBI SEIZED A COMPUTER.
ONE OF THE THINGS THEY KNOW IS
HE WAS PLAYING PRETTY VIOLENT
VIDEO GAMES, REENACTING BATTLE
SCENES WITH GRAPHIC CHARACTERS
AND SO ON.
I WAS DEBATING THIS ON TWITTER
TODAY, IF YOU'RE WATCHING AND
WANT TO GET INVOLVED IN ANY OF
THIS, TELL ME, MANY HAVE BEEN
STRONG ABOUT ALL THESE THINGS.
PEOPLE SAYING THERE'S NO LINK
BETWEEN ANY OF THIS AND ANYONE
WATCHING VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES,
BUT HERE'S MY QUESTION.
IN ALL YOUR EXPERIENCE, IF
SOMEBODY IS MENTALLY ILL,
MENTALLY UNSTABLE, VULNERABLE,
IF YOU LIKE, AND THEY ARE
WATCHING VERY VIOLENT VIDEO
GAMES A LOT, CAN IT STIMULATE
THEM, DOES IT DESENSITIZE THEM,
CAN IT BE PART OF THE
PROVOCATION, IF YOU LIKE, FOR
MAKING THEM GO AND DO AN
ATROCITY?
>> I DON'T THINK IT'S PART OF
THE PROVOCATION.
LET ME SAY SOMETHING.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT MENTAL
ILLNESS, DOESN'T MEAN YOU'RE
MENTALLY UNSTABLE.
THE MAJORITY OF PEOPLE IN
TREATMENT WITH SERIOUS MENTAL
ILLNESSES LIKES ASPERGER'S,
SCHIZOPHRENIA, BIPOLAR, ARE
STABLE, LIVING PRODUCTIVE LIVES,
ARE WORKING.
LET'S BE REALLY CLEAR ABOUT
THAT.
WHAT HAPPENS, I LOOK AT THAT
RESEARCH FOR MANY, MANY YEARS.
THERE WAS AN ATTEMPT TO BAN --
>> COLUMBINE ALSO.
>> THE HEADLINE IS THAT, YES,
WHEN YOU'RE ENGAGED IN, YOU
KNOW, VERY VIVID VIDEOS WHERE
YOU'RE SHOOTING PEOPLE, KILLING
PEOPLE, WHAT HAPPENS IS YOU'RE
DESENSITIZED TO WHAT IT MEANS TO
PULL A TRIGGER.
CERTAINLY, THE SCIENCE THERE IS
VERY GOOD, BUT A LOT OF THAT
RESEARCH IS FLAWED IN THAT
PEOPLE ARE SELECTED NOT -- YOU
CAN'T KNOW AHEAD OF TIME IF THE
PEOPLE WHO ARE DRAWN TO THESE
GAMES ARE ALREADY PEOPLE PRONE
TO VIOLENCE AND AGGRESSION,
REGARDLESS OF THE ISSUE OF
MENTAL ILLNESS.
>> PEOPLE WHO PLAY THESE GAMES
ARE PERFECTLY NORMAL, WHATEVER
NORMAL MEANS THESE DAYS, AND IT
HAS NO AFFECT ON THEM, I TOTALLY
ACCEPT THAT.
ANOTHER ARGUMENT THAT'S BEEN
RAISING, MORGAN FREEMAN, THE
ACTOR, BLAMED THE MEDIA FOR ALL
OF THIS, COPYCAT SYNDROME, THE
MEDIA, BY MAKING AS HE PUT IT
ALMOST LIKE GROTESQUE HEROS OF
THESE PEOPLE BY CONSTANTLY
NAMING THEM, SOMEHOW PROPAGATE
THIS ONGOING SITUATION WITH SO
MANY MASS SHOOTINGS.
DO YOU THINK HE'S RIGHT?
I MEAN, I DIDN'T AGREE WITH HIM
RULING OUT GUN CONTROL --
>> I DON'T THINK HE'S RIGHT.
>> IS HE RIGHT?
>> NO, HE'S NOT.
I'LL BLAME THE MEDIA FOR ONE
THING ONLY, WHICH IS
RETRAUMATIZING US.
DO YOU REMEMBER WITH 9/11 THERE
WAS A CALL FOR THE MEDIA TO STOP
SHOWING THE JETS FLYING INTO THE
BUILDINGS, BECAUSE PSYCHOLOGISTS
LIKE MYSELF AND OTHERS WERE
SEEING OUR PATIENTS HAVING VIVID
FLASHBACKS, NIGHTMARES,
POST-TRAUMATIC STRESS DISORDER
REACTION.
EXCESSIVE COVERAGE OF THIS CAN
BE TRAUMATIZING.
I'VE LOOKED AT PICTURES OF DEAD
CHILDREN AND BABIES IN THE CASES
I'VE WORKED ON AND HAD
NIGHTMARES.
ONE CASE IN PARTICULAR I STILL
HAVE FLASHBACKS TO JUST LOOKING
AT PICTURES, BUT NO, IT DOESN'T
CAUSE THIS KIND OF THING.
CAN I SAY ONE THING REALLY,
REALLY CLEARLY THAT I ONLY
TOUCHED ON ON FRIDAY, YOUR
CHANCES OF BEING SHOT AND KILLED
IN A MASS SHOOTING LIKE THIS ARE
ACTUALLY LESS THAN BEING STRUCK
BY LIGHTNING.
I'M NOT SAYING WE SHOULDN'T
COVER THIS AND TALK ABOUT THIS,
BUT, YOU KNOW, I'M SORRY, MORGAN
FREEMAN, THIS IS NOT CAUSING --
>> I'M HEARING APPARENTLY MORGAN
FREEMAN HAS COME OUT AND SAID
IT'S A HOAX, ALTHOUGH IT'S BEEN
RUNNING ALL OVER THE MEDIA FOR
THE LAST 24 HOURS.
IT MAY BE A HOAX, AS HE APPEARS
TO NOW BE CLARIFYING.
EITHER WAY, THOUGH, IT'S A
DEBATE A LOT OF PEOPLE I'VE BEEN
SEEING ON TWITTER, CNN ANCHORS,
ANDERSON COOPER AND OTHERS THINK
YOU SHOULDN'T BE NAMING.
IT'S SOMETHING PEOPLE SHOULD BE
THINKING ABOUT QUITE CAREFULLY.
>> IT IS A VALID THING TO BE
THINKING ABOUT, BUT THEN YOU
TURN TO THE RESEARCH, IF YOU
HAVE VIABLE RESEARCH TO LOOK AT,
YOU CAN LOOK AT EXPERTS WHO CAN
ASSESS THE TRUTHFULNESS OF THE
CONCLUSIONS.
WE DON'T SEE THAT COVERAGE LIKE
THIS CAUSES VIOLENCE.
>> FINAL QUESTION, EVERYBODY
WANTS TO KNOW THE SAME THING,
WHY WOULD A 20-YEAR-OLD BOY WHO
JUST SEEMED TO BE A LITTLE BIT
OF A LONER, LITTLE BIT STRANGE,
BUT NOTHING DANGEROUS AT ALL,
WHY WOULD HE GO TO A SCHOOL AND
KILL 20, 5, 6, 7-YEAR-OLD KIDS?
>> THE PERSON THAT HAS THE
ANSWER MAYBE IS ADAM.
ONE THING WE KNOW IS PEOPLE WITH
MENTAL ILLNESSES AND PEOPLE WHO
DON'T HAVE MENTAL ILLNESSES WHO
DO THESE THINGS ISOLATE
THEMSELVES FIRST.
WHAT WE NEED TO DO IS BUILD
BRIDGES TO THESE PEOPLE.
I TELL YOU WHAT, THE PEOPLE WHO
ARE VIOLENT AND ARE PRONE TO
SUICIDE, IN MY FIELD, WE PREVENT
THOSE KINDS OF THINGS ALL THE
TIME WHEN WE BUILD A
RELATIONSHIP WITH THE PERSON.
THEY WILL TALK TO ME, YOU KNOW
WHAT, DOC, I'M SO ANGRY I'M
THINKING ABOUT KILLING MY
MOTHER.
>> HIS COMPUTER HARD DRIVE THE
FBI HAVE.
>>> WHEN WE COME BACK, WHAT TO
DO ABOUT GUNS.
IT'S TRULY A QUESTION ABOUT LIFE
AND DEATH AND FEELINGS ON BOTH
SIDES ARE VERY MOTIVE.
I'LL TALK TO BOTH SIDES AFTER
THE BREAK.
AMERICANS BELIEVE THEY SHOULD BE
IN CHARGE OF THEIR OWN FUTURE.
HOW THEY'LL LIVE TOMORROW.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
wSecondhand smoke affects
everyone's health.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
It's not just irritating.
It can cause heart disease
and even death.
Speak up about
secondhand smoke.
Your health and the health
of your family depend on it.
>>> AND WE WILL HAVE TO CHANGE.
SINCE I'VE BEEN PRESIDENT, THIS
IS THE FOURTH TIME WE HAVE COME
TOGETHER TO COMFORT A GRIEVING
COMMUNITY TORN APART BY MASS
SHOOTINGS.
FOURTH TIME WE'VE HUGGED
SURVIVORS, THE FOURTH TIME WE'VE
CONSOLED THE FAMILIES OF
VICTIMS.
AND IN BETWEEN, THERE HAVE BEEN
AN ENDLESS SERIES OF DEADLY
SHOOTINGS ACROSS THE COUNTRY,
ALMOST DAILY REPORTS OF VICTIMS,
MANY OF THEM CHILDREN.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA IN TONIGHT'S
VIGIL CALLING FOR CHANGE, BUT
THE QUESTION REMAINS WHAT
AMERICA SHOULD DO ABOUT GUNS.
PRESIDENT OF THE BRADY CAMPAIGN
TO PREVENT GUN VIOLENCE AND THE
ATTORNEY FOR THE MICHIGAN
COALITION FOR RESPONSIBLE GUN
OWNERS.
I WANT YOUR REACTION, FIRST OF
ALL, DAN GROSS, WHAT DO YOU MAKE
OF HOW THE PRESIDENT SAID, AND
HOW SERIOUS DO YOU THINK HE IS
ABOUT ACTUALLY DOING SOMETHING
RATHER THAN JUST WORDS?
>> WE'RE INSPIRED.
I MEAN, WE'RE INSPIRED TO TAKE
HIM AT HIS WORD.
THE PRESIDENT, SINCE THIS HAS
HAPPENED, HAS CALLED FOR
MEANINGFUL ACTION.
HE'S SAYING ALL THE RIGHT
THINGS, AND HE'S TALKING ABOUT
ALL THE RIGHT THINGS.
IT'S UP TO US, THE AMERICAN
PUBLIC NOW, INCLUDING ALL THE
VICTIMS THAT HAVE BEEN IMPACTED
BY THESE TRAGEDIES, TO MAKE SURE
HE DOES TAKE THAT ACTION.
THOSE ARE THE DOTS THAT NEED TO
BE CONNECTED.
THIS IS THE TIME.
CHANGE HAS TO HAPPEN.
AND THIS REALLY IS A PIVOTAL
MOMENT IN THE HISTORY OF THIS
ISSUE, AND YOU CAN JUST SENSE IT
WATCHING THIS TONIGHT AND SEEING
HOW THAT COMMUNITY IS GRIEVING
AND KNOWING HOW OUR WHOLE NATION
IS GRIEVING.
WE DO THINK THIS IS A TIME FOR
CHANGE AND WE DO THINK PRESIDENT
OBAMA IS GOING TO LEAD US IN THE
RIGHT DIRECTION.
>> STEVE, THE NATURE OF THIS
DEBATE, I THINK, NEEDS TO BE
CRYSTALLIZED AND CLARIFIED.
TOO MANY PEOPLE ON EACH SIDES
TAKE EXTREME POSITIONS AND PUT
WORDS IN THE MOUTH OF THEIR
OPPONENTS.
YOU THE REALITY IS THIS, NOBODY
IS SUGGESTING A BAN ON ALL GUNS
IN AMERICA.
THE SECOND AMENDMENT IS
ABSOLUTELY PART OF AMERICAN
CULTURE AND PEOPLE BELIEVE IN
IT.
HOWEVER, THERE ARE LIMITATIONS.
THE AMENDMENT TALKS ABOUT A
WELL-REGULATED MILITIA.
PEOPLE ARE CALLING OUT FOR
TAKING SOME OF THESE WEAPONS
AWAY FROM PEOPLE WITH POTENTIAL
MENTAL ISSUES.
TO ME, THE QUESTION FOR YOU IS
IS, THE LAST THREE MASS
SHOOTINGS IN THE LAST FOUR
MONTHS IN AMERICA, AURORA,
OREGON IN THE SHOPPING MALL AND
NOW HERE IN NEWTOWN HAVE
INVOLVED YOUNG PEOPLE USING THE
SAME WEAPON, AR-15
SEMI-AUTOMATIC RIFLE WITH
HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINES.
IN AURORA, OVER 100 IN HIS
MAGAZINE, WHICH HE COULD FIRE
OFF, AND HERE WE SAW UP TO 30,
BUT A LOT OF MAGAZINES.
HERE'S THE QUESTION, WHY DO YOU
FEEL THAT AMERICANS SHOULD HAVE
THOSE IF YOUR BELIEF IS THEY
JUST HAVE TO DEFEND THEMSELVES?
>> WELL, BEFORE I GO ANY
FURTHER, PIERS, FIRST, THANKS
FOR HAVING ME BACK.
WE DID HAVE A HEATED DISCUSSION
LAST TIME AND I MUCH APPRECIATE
THIS MORE CALM DISCUSSION.
SECOND, ON BEHALF OF I'M SURE I
SPEAK FOR THE ENTIRE BOARD OF
MICHIGAN COALITION OF
RESPONSIBLE GUN OWNERS WE OFFER
OUR CONDOLENCES FOR THE VICTIMS
OF THE FAMILIES.
WE ARE ALL ABOUT SAFETY.
WE ALL WANT TO BE SAFE AND WE
CERTAINLY WANT CHILDREN TO BE
SAFE.
LIKE I SAID LAST WEEK, WE JUST
DISAGREE ON HOW TO GET THERE
FROM HERE.
TO ANSWER YOUR QUESTION, I WOULD
POINT OUT THAT THE SHOOTER IN
THE MALL IN OREGON WAS
CONFRONTED BY A LEGALLY ARMED
CITIZEN WHO POINTED HIS GUN AT
THE SHOOTER AND THEN DECIDED NOT
TO SQUEEZE THE TRIGGER BECAUSE
HE WAS AFRAID OF MISSING AND
HITTING BYSTANDERS.
HE WAS ACTING VERY RESPONSIBLY.
AND THE NEXT SHOT THAT THAT
SHOOTER FIRED, THAT THE KILLER
FIRED, WAS ON HIMSELF AFTER HE
WAS CONFRONTED WITH AN ARMED
CITIZEN.
SO THAT'S ACTUALLY ONE EXAMPLE
OF A RESPONSIBLE GUN OWNER USING
A GUN TO SAVE LIVES.
>> WELL, HE ACTUALLY DIDN'T USE
THE GUN.
I THINK THE POINT, DAN, UNLESS
I'M MISTAKEN.
YOU TAKE IT UP HERE.
BUT I DON'T THINK ANY AMERICAN
CITIZEN WITH A LEGAL GUN HAS
EVER INTERVENED IN A MASS
SHOOTING, CERTAINLY NOT IN THE
LAST 30 OR 40 YEARS IN AMERICA.
>> ACTUALLY, THEY HAVE.
>> BEFORE THIS EVOLVES INTO AN
ARGUMENT, I MEAN, AS EASY AS IT
IS TO BECOME UNINSPIRED BY A
CONVERSATION LIKE THIS AND WHAT
YOUR OTHER GUEST IS SAYING, I
JUST ENCOURAGE THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE TO NOT LOSE THE SENSE OF
INSPIRATION IN TERMS OF THE
CHANGE THAT WE HAVE THE
POTENTIAL TO ACCOMPLISH.
THIS IS NOT THE CONVERSATION
THAT THE AMERICAN PUBLIC WANT TO
HAVE.
THIS IS NOT OUR VISION WHERE THE
ANSWER TO VIOLENCE IS MORE
VIOLENCE, WHERE THE ANSWER TO
GUNS IS MORE GUNS.
THERE IS FERTILE GROUND WHERE
THE OVERWHELMING MAJORITY OF
AMERICANS AGREE WITH THINGS LIKE
BACKGROUND CHECKS TO MAKE SURE
THAT 40% OF ALL GUN SALES THAT
ARE NOT CURRENTLY COVERED BY
BACKGROUND CHECKS TO PREVENT
MENTALLY ILL PEOPLE FROM GETTING
GUNS, TO PREVENT CRIMINALS AND
DOMESTIC ABUSERS FROM GETTING
GUNS, TO CLOSE THAT GAPING HOLE
IN OUR SYSTEM.
GUN OWNERS, 74% OF NRA MEMBERS
SUPPORT SOLUTIONS LIKE THAT.
UNFORTUNATELY, SOMETIMES THIS
PLAYS OUT AS A POLARIZED
POLITICAL DEBATE IN SEGMENTS
LIKE THE ONE I WAS PART OF ALSO
ON FRIDAY NIGHT, BUT THE REALITY
IS THE AMERICAN PUBLIC ISN'T
POLARIZED.
THE ONLY PLACE THIS IS A
POLARIZED POLITICAL DEBATE IS IN
CONGRESS.
WE NEED TO TAKE THE VOICE OF THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE WHO KNOW THAT,
AS PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID TONIGHT,
WE CAN BE BETTER THAN THIS AND
HOLD OUR LEADERS ACCOUNTABLE.
>> VERY INTERESTING TO ME.
THIS IS ALMOST A MIRROR TRAGEDY
OF WHAT HAPPENED IN BRITAIN IN
1996 AND SCOTLAND, 16 YOUNG 5
AND 6-YEAR-OLD CHILDREN WERE
KILLED.
IT WAS THE WORST SHOOTING OF ITS
TYPE IN MODERN AMERICAN HISTORY,
AND AS A RESULT, A FULL HANDGUN
BAN WAS BROUGHT IN.
WHICH WOULD NOT BE APPLICABLE
HERE, THERE ARE TOO MANY IN
CIRCULATION.
BUT WHAT WAS MOST NOTABLE ABOUT
THE DEBATE, IT WAS COMPLETELY
NON-POLITICAL.
MY QUESTION FOR YOU, STEVE, IS
WHY DOES THIS HAVE TO BE
POLITICAL?
WHY CAN IT NOT JUST BE A
BIPARTISAN, ALL ENCOMPASSING,
AMERICAN DIALOGUE, WHICH LEADS
IN THE END TO PRAGMATIC
SOLUTION?
>> I AGREE WITH YOUR LAST
STATEMENT, ABSOLUTELY, PIERS.
IN FACT, OUR GROUP IS A SINGLE
ISSUE NON-PARTISAN GROUP.
WE HAVE INDEPENDENTS, DEMOCRATS,
AND REPUBLICANS IN OUR GROUP AND
ON MEMBERSHIP, MOST ARE ELECTED
OFFICIALS.
WE ACTUALLY DO TAKE THAT
POSITION.
>> DO YOU AGREE WITH UNIVERSAL
BACKGROUND CHECKS?
>> UNIVERSAL BACKGROUND CHECKS?
YOU KNOW WE HAVE THE CRIMINAL
BACKGROUND CHECK IN PLACE.
>> RIGHT, BUT THAT ONLY APPLIES
TO 60% OF GUN SALES.
DO YOU AGREE WITH COVERING THE
OTHER 40% OF GUN SALES WITH
BACKGROUND CHECKS?
>> WE AGREE THAT DISQUALIFIED
INDIVIDUALS SHOULD NOT HAVE
ACCESS TO FIREARMS.
>> SO YOU AGREE WITH THE
BACKGROUND CHECKS --
>> ARE YOU GOING TO LET ME
FINISH?
PLEASE, PLEASE.
>> LET ME ASK YOU, GIVE ME ONE
GOOD REASON WHY THERE SHOULDN'T
BE 100% BACKGROUND CHECKS ON ALL
GUN TRANSACTIONS IN AMERICA.
GIVE ME A GOOD REASON.
>> IT'S LITERALLY IMPOSSIBLE,
PIERS, AS YOU POINTED OUT A
MOMENT AGO, TO DO 100%.
WE HAVE A LOT OF GUNS IN
CIRCULATION ON EARTH AND IN THE
UNITED STATES.
WE KNOW THAT GUNS PASS ACROSS
BORDERS.
>> WE'RE TALKING ABOUT NEW ONES.
>> NATIONAL AND STATE BORDERS.
>> LET ME FOCUS THE QUESTION
MORE SOLIDLY AND REALISTICALLY.
NEW GUNS PURCHASED FROM THIS DAY
FORWARD, WOULD YOU BE SUPPORTIVE
OF 100% REGISTRATION,
ACCOUNTABILITY, DATABASE, A
NATIONAL DATABASE, AND IF YOU'RE
NOT IN FAVOR OF THAT, WHY
WOULDN'T YOU BE?
>> OR AS CLOSE AS WE CAN GET TO
100%, WHICH IS A LOT CLOSER THAN
WHERE WE ARE NOW.
>> THE SYSTEM WE HAVE IN PLACE
RIGHT NOW IS A LIST OF THOSE
DISQUALIFIED.
PERSONALLY, I WOULD SUPPORT THAT
BASED ON EVERYTHING I'VE BEEN
ABLE TO LEARN IN MY POSITION AS
PROFESSOR OF FIREARMS LAW AND IN
MY POSITION AS A TRAINER OF
CONCEALED PISTOL LICENSES THAT
NATIONAL INSTANT CHECK SYSTEM
SEEMS TO BE WORKING QUITE WELL.
I BELIEVE THAT'S ONE AREA
EVERYONE AGREES.
>> WE SHOULD APPLY TO 100% OF
GUN SALES?
>> WE HAVE A LIST OF FOLKS WHO
ARE DISQUALIFIED WHO HAVE BEEN
ADJUDICATED MENTALLY ILL, FELONY
RECORDS THAT DISQUALIFY THEM, ET
CETERA.
THAT SYSTEM SEEMS TO WORK QUITE
WELL.
>> FINAL QUESTION FOR YOU,
STEVE, IS THIS.
IN LIGHT OF THE FACT THE LAST
THREE MASS SHOOTINGS, AS I SAID,
ALL FEATURED AN AR-15 RIFLE
AIDED AND ABETTED BY
HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINES, GIVE ME
A REASON WHY YOU ARE COMFORTABLE
WITH THOSE WEAPONS STILL BEING
SOLD IN CONNECTION WITH
HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINES IN
AMERICA IN PLACES LIKE WALMART.
>> FAIR ENOUGH.
AND I DON'T KNOW ANY PARTICULAR
RETAILER, BUT I WILL SAY WE DID
TRY FROM 1994 TO 2004, WE TRIED
THE SO-CALLED ASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN.
IT HAD NO IMPACT ON CRIME THAT
ANYONE COULD MEASURE WHATSOEVER,
AND THE TRUTH IS SOMETIMES THESE
GUNS ARE USED IN VERY POSITIVE
WAYS TO SAVE LIVES.
THEY ARE FUNCTIONALLY IDENTICAL
TO SEMI-AUTOMATIC WEAPONS THAT
DATE BACK LITERALLY TO THE
1800s.
A HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINE IS
NOTHING BUT A STEEL BOX AND A
SPRING.
IT'S INCREDIBLY EASY TO MAKE A
HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINE.
THE TRUTH IS THAT ANY SUCH BAN
WOULD BE INEFFECTIVE.
>> THIS IS TOTALLY DISCONNECTED
WITH WHAT THE AMERICAN PEOPLE
WANT AND THE CONVERSATION THAT'S
HAPPENING OUT THERE, AND THAT'S
WHAT GIVES ME INSPIRATION TO
CONTINUE TO HAVE CONVERSATIONS
LIKE THIS.
THE AMERICAN PUBLIC KNOWS WE ARE
BETTER THAN THIS.
WE DON'T WANT TO LIVE IN A
SOCIETY WHERE VIOLENCE LEADS TO
MORE VIOLENCE AND GUNS LEAD TO
MORE GUNS.
THAT'S THE CONVERSATION
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS LEADING AND
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE NEED TO
SPEAK UP AROUND.
>> GOT TO LEAVE IT THERE.
>> WE ALL AGREE WE NEED SAFETY.
>> WE'RE ALL AGREED ON THAT.
WE WILL CONTINUE THIS DEBATE ON
THE SHOW.
IT'S BEEN AN IMPORTANT ONE FOR
AMERICA.
THANK YOU BOTH.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID WE
CAN'T TOLERATE THIS ANYMORE, BUT
WILL THERE BE A CHANGE IN
POLICY?
I'LL ASK FRANK BRUNI AFTER THE
BREAK.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS AMY. AMY LIKES
TO INVEST IN THE MARKET.
SHE ALSO LIKES
TO RIDE HER BIKE.
SHE KNOWS THE POTENTIAL
FOR MAKING OR LOSING MONEY
CAN POP UP ANYTIME.
THAT'S WHY SHE TRADES WITH
THE LEADER IN MOBILE TRADING.
SO SHE'S ALWAYS READY
TO TAKE ACTION,
NO MATTER HOW WILY...
OR WEIRD...
OR WONDERFULLY
THE MARKET'S BEHAVING...
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.