>>> AND WE'LL BE GOING BACK TO
DON LEMON IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
IN JUST ABOUT SEVERAL HOURS,
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS SCHEDULED TO
ARRIVE THERE IN NEWTOWN.
EEL MEET WITH FAMILIES OF THE 26
VICTIMS KILLED IN FRIDAY'S MASS
SHOOTING AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE PRESIDENT WILL ALSO SPEAK AT
AN INTERFAITH VIGIL.
WE'LL BE BRINGING YOU THAT
SERVICE LIVE AT 7:00 P.M.
EASTERN.
WE'RE FOLLOWING THE LATEST
DEVELOPMENTS ON THE SHOOTING
INVESTIGATION.
HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW RIGHT NOW.
CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR, DAN
MALLOY, SAYS THE 20-YEAR-OLD
SUSPECT SHOT HIS WAY INTO THE
SCHOOL.
WE'VE ALSO LEARNED THAT ALL 20
OF THE CHILDREN KILLED INSIDE
WERE SHOT MULTIPLE TIMES.
ALL OF THEM WERE SIX AND SEVEN
YEARS OLD.
INVESTIGATORS ARE STILL
PROCESSING THE CRIME SCENE.
PHYSICALLY AND FORENSICALLY.
POLICE SAY THEY EXPECT ALL
QUESTIONS SURROUNDING THE CASE
WILL ULTIMATELY BE ANSWERED
BECAUSE THEY HAVE FOUND CERTAIN
EVIDENCE.
MEDICAL EXAMINER'S OFFICE IS
STARTING TO RELEASE THE BODIES
OF THE 26 VICTIMS BACK TO THEIR
FAMILIES AND FUNERALS ARE
EXPECTED TO BE HELD THIS WEEK.
>>> THE SUSPECTED GUNMAN'S
FATHER, PETER LANZA, IS
EXPRESSING CONDOLENCES TO THE
VICTIM'S FAMILIES.
RELEASED A STATEMENT SAYING
QUOTE, WE'RE IN A STATE OF
DISBELIEF.
TRYING TO FIND WHATEVER ANSWERS
WE CAN.
WE, TOO, ARE ASKING WHY.
WE'VE COOPERATED FULLY WITH LAW
ENFORCEMENT AND WILL CONTINUE TO
DO SO WE'RE SADDENED, BUT
STRUGGLING TO MAKE SENSE OF WHAT
HAS TRANSPIRED.
WE'RE GOING TO GO TO DON LEMON
IN NEWTOWN.
SO MUCH GOING ON.
SO DIFFICULT, EVEN FOR THE
FATHER TO HAVE TO PUT IN CONTEXT
THAT ALLEGEDLY HIS SON IS THE
ONE WHO CAUSED SO MUCH GRIEF AND
SO MUCH PAIN FOR ALL OF THESE
FAMILIES, TARGETING AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> YEAH, IT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
IT'S REALLY UNBEARABLE TO THINK
ABOUT, DEB, A SON GETTING GUNS
FROM HIS OWN HOME AND GOING ON A
KILLING RAMPAGE.
OUR BRIAN TODD WHO WENT OUT AND
SPOKE WITH SOME PEOPLE WHO KNOW
THE SHOOTING SUSPECT.
>> HIS MOTIVE FOR THIS
UNSPEAKABLE ACT IS STILL NOT
CLEAR.
LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS SAY.
AND IN DIGGING FOR DETAILS ABOUT
SHOOTER ADAM LANZA AND HIS
FAMILY.
ACCOUNTS EMERGE THAT ARE STILL
CONFUSING, SOMETIMES
CONFLICTING.
A NEIGHBOR WHO KNEW HIM IN
RECENT YEARS DESCRIBES LANZA AS
TROUBLED.
BUT LISTEN TO THIS ACCOUNT FROM
A YOUNG MAN WHO KNEW HIM.
>> HE WAS JUST A KID.
>> JUST A KID.
>> NEVER ANTI-SOCIAL?
>> NO, ADAM, NO.
>> TROUBLE-MAKE CENTRE.
>> NO, DEFINITELY NOT.
>> NOTICEABLE?
DID HE JUST KIND OF BLEND INTO
THE BACKGROUND?
>> YEAH.
NOTHING THAT WOULD WARRANT ANY
OF THIS.
>> RYAN CRAFT SAYS HE BABYSAT
ADAM LANZA ABOUT TEN YEARS AGO
WHEN LANZA WAS TEN AND CRAFT WAS
15.
HE DESCRIBES LANZA AS FOCUSED,
QUIET, INTROVERTED.
HE NEVER SAW EVIDENCE OF
VIOLENCE, CRAFT SAYS.
BUT SAYS LANZA DID THROW THE
OCCASIONAL TEMPER TANTRUM.
>> JUST GENERAL STUFF LIKE YOU
WOULD HAVE TO PUT HIM TO BED AND
HE WOULDN'T LIKE THAT.
OR WE HAD TO STOP WATCHING TV,
AND HE WOULDN'T LIKE THAT.
NORMAL STUFF THAT KIDS DO, BUT I
GUESS AT 10 YEARS OLD, KIDS GET
OUT OF THAT PHASE, BUT THAT
WASN'T THE CASE FOR ADAM.
>> MOTHER TOLD HIM TO LET RYAN
DO WHATEVER HE WANTED.
BUT AS FOR ADAM --
>> NANCY ALWAYS ASKED ME TO
ALWAYS BE WITH HIM IN THE ROOM.
NO MATTER WHAT.
DON'T GO TO THE BATHROOM, DON'T
EVER LEAVE HIM WITHOUT
SUPERVISION.
>> CRAFT SAYS ADAM HAD A
CONTENTIOUS RELATIONSHIP WITH
HIS MOTHER, NANCY.
SHE HAD SPLIT FROM THE BOY'S
FATHER, PETE ELANZA, WHO IS TAX
DIRECTOR AND PRESIDENT OF GEES
IFS BUT KRAFT SAYS NANCY LANZA
WAS AN ENGAGED MOTHER, SETTING
UP PLAY DATES WITH HER SONS AND
TAKING PART IN NEIGHBORHOOD
ACTIVITIES.
NEIGHBORS SAY NANCY LANZA
ENJOYED GARDENING AND HAD TAKEN
TIME OFF FROM HER JOB IN
FINANCE.
>> DECORATE THE HOUSE, THE HOUSE
WAS ALWAYS PRISTINE AND, I MEAN
SHE WAS JUST LIKE ANY OTHER
HOUSEWIFE.
>> BUT LIKE HER SON, THERE ARE
GAPS IN NANCY LANZA'S STORY THAT
STILL NEED TO BE FILLED IN.
SHE OWNED THE WEAPONS THAT ADAM
LANZA USED IN THE KILLINGS,
INCLUDING A SEMI AUTOMATIC RIVAL
AND IT'S NOT CLEAR WHY SHE
PURCHASED THEM.
BRIAN TODD, CNN, WASHINGTON.
>>> WELL, THERE IS OTHER NEWS AS
WELL IN WASHINGTON, HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER HAS AGREED
TO RAISE TAXES ON THE RICH TO
AVERT THE FISCAL CLIFF.
A SOURCE TELLS CNN THAT BOEHNER
HAS OFFERED TO RAISE TAX RATES
ON PEOPLE MAKING MORE THAN $1
MILLION IN EXCHANGE FOR
ENTITLEMENT CUTS, THE WHITE
HOUSE IS STILL HOLDING TO THE
$250,000 THRESHOLD.
UNLESS A DEAL IS REACHED BY
JANUARY 1st, 98% OF AMERICANS
WILL BE HIT WITH A TAX INCREASE.
>>> EGYPT'S MUSLIM BROTHERHOOD
DECLARE AS NARROW VICTORY IN THE
FIRST ROUND OF HOTLY CONTESTED
CONSTITUTIONAL REFERENDUM.
THIS IS THE ONLY FIRST WEEKEND
OF VOTING, THE REST OF THE
COUNTRY WILL VOTE NEXT WEEKEND.
ELECTION MONITOR REPORT SOME
CLAIMS OF VOTER INTIMIDATION, AS
WELL AS EARLY POLL CLOSINGS.
>>> FORMER SOUTH AFRICAN
PRESIDENT, NELSON MANDALA IS
RECOVERING IN A HOSPITAL IN
PRETORIA.
THE 94-YEAR-OLD NOBEL LAUREATE
HAD GALL STONES REMOVED
YESTERDAY.
HE WAS HOSPITALIZED LAST WEEKEND
FOR A LUNG INFECTION, HE'S BEEN
KEEPING A LOW PROFILE FOR YEARS
AND IS HAILED AS A HERO OF
DEMOCRACY IN SOUTH AFRICA.
>>> WELL, A MESSAGE OF HOPE IN
THE WAKE OF UNSPEAKABLE
HEARTBREAK.
THE FATHER OF ONE OF THE
CHILDREN KILLED IN CONNECTICUT
OFFER AS MESSAGE OF LOVE AND
RECONCILIATION.
[ Woman ] DEAR CAT, YOUR HAIR
MIXES WITH POLLEN AND DUST.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
♪ OOH BABY,
CAN I DO FOR YOU TODAY? ♪
[ Female Announcer ] NEED HELP
KEEPING YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE?
ALIGN CAN HELP.
ONLY ALIGN HAS BIFANTIS,
A PATENTED PROBIOTIC
THAT NATURALLY HELPS MAINTAIN
YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE.
TRY ALIGN TO HELP RETAIN
A BALANCED DIGESTIVE SYSTEM.
TRY THE #1 GASTROENTEROLOGIST
RECOMMENDED PROBIOTIC.
ALIGN.
>>> FOX TELEVISION HAS PULLED
EPISODES OF THEIR POPULAR
COMEDIES "FAMILY GUY" AND
"AMERICAN DAD" THAT WERE
SUPPOSED TO AIR TONIGHT OUT OF
RESPECT FOR THE SCHOOL SHOOTING
VICTIMS, TOM CRUISE WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE IN PITTSBURGH LAST NIGHT
FOR THE PREVIEW OF HIS NEW MOVIE
"JACK REACHER."
BUT THE STUDIO CANCELED EVENT
BECAUSE OF THE SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT.
THE FILM BEGINS WITH A SCENE
INVOLVING A SNIPER ATTACK.
>>> AND TODAY, THE NFL TEAMS
PLAYING IN EIGHT DIFFERENT
GAMES, THEY'RE ALL PLANNING TO
DO SOME KIND OF REMEMBRANCE.
WE NOW GO BACK TO DON LEMON WHO
IS IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
DON?
>> AS WELL THEY SHOULD DO SOME
TYPE OF REMEMBRANCE.
LAST NIGHT FRIENDS AND MOURNERS
GATHERED IN STRATFORD,
CONNECTICUT TO REMEMBER SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY TEACHER,
VICTORIA SOTO.
♪
>> YOU CAN SEE SEVERAL PEOPLE IN
THE CROWD WERE WEARING GREEN,
THAT WAS VICTORIA'S FAVORITE
COLOR.
THE FIRST GRADE TEACHER WAS
KILLED ON FRIDAY MORNING.
SHE DIED TRYING TO PROTECT HER
STUDENTS, VICTORIA SOTO WAS 27
YEARS OLD.
EMILIE PARKER WAS SIX YEARS OLD,
SHE IS ANOTHER VICTIM OF THE
TRAGEDY AND HER FATHER SPOKE
PUBLICLY LAST NIGHT.
HE IS THE ONLY PARENT TO COME
FORWARD PUBLICLY IT TALK ABOUT
THEIR TERRIBLE LOSS, BECAUSE HE
WANTS EVERYONE TO KNOW HOW
SPECIAL HIS LITTLE GIRL WAS.
>> I WOULD REALLY LIKE.
>> TO OFFER OUR DEEPEST
CONDOLENCES TO ALL OF THE
FAMILIES DIRECTLY AFFECTED BY
THE SHOOTING.
IT'S A HORRIFIC TRAGEDY AND WE
WANT EVERYBODY TO KNOW THAT OUR
HEARTS AND PRAYERS GO OUT TO
THEM.
THIS INCLUDES THE FAMILY OF THE
SHOOTER.
I CAN'T IMAGINE HOW HARD THIS
EXPERIENCE MUST BE FOR YOU.
AND I WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT OUR
FAMILY AND OUR LOVE AND OUR
SUPPORT GOES OUT TO YOU AS WELL.
MY DAUGHTER EMILIE, WOULD BE ONE
OF THE FIRST ONES TO BE STANDING
AND GIVING HER LOVE AND SUPPORT
TO ALL THOSE VICTIMS.
BECAUSE THAT'S THE TYPE OF
PERSON THAT SHE IS.
NOT BECAUSE OF ANY PARENTING
THAT MY WIFE AND I COULD HAVE
DONE, BUT BECAUSE THOSE ARE THE
GIFTS THAT WERE GIVEN TO YOU BY
HER HEAVENLY FATHER.
I HAVE TWO REALLY GOOD FRIENDS
AT HOME WHO HAVE SET UP A
FACEBOOK PAGE.
TO HELP RAISE MONEY FOR EMILIE.
AND WHEN I'VE GOTTEN ON THAT AND
SEEN THE NUMBER OF PEOPLE WHO
HAVE COMMENTED AND EXPRESSED
THEIR CONDOLENCES, IT'S BEEN
QUITE OVERWHELMING.
AS THE DEAN PAIN BEGINS TO
SETTLE INTO OUR HEARTS, WE FIND
COMFORT REFLECTING ON THE
INCREDIBLE PERSON THAT EMILIE
WAS.
AND HOW MANY LIVES THAT SHE WAS
ABLE TO TOUCH IN HER SHORT TIME
HERE ON EARTH.
EMILIE WAS BRIGHT, CREATIVE AND
VERY LOVING.
EMILIE WAS ALWAYS WILLING TO TRY
NEW THINGS.
OTHER THAN FOOD.
SHE LOVED TO USE HER TALENTS TO
TOUCH THE LIVES OF EVERYONE SHE
CAME IN CONTACT WITH SHE WAS AN
EXCEPTIONAL ART IFRT AND SHE
ALWAYS CARRIED AROUND HER
MARKERS AND PENCILS SO SHE NEVER
MISSED AND OPPORTUNITY TO DRAW A
PICTURE OR MAKE A CARD FOR THOSE
AROUND HER.
I CAN'T COUNT THE NUMBER OF
TIMES EMILIE NOTICED SOMEONE
FEELING SAD OR FRUSTRATED AND
WOULD RUSH TO FIND A PIECE OF
PAPER TO DRAW THEM A PICTURE OR
TO WRITE THEM AN ENCOURAGING
NOTE.
EMILIE'S CARD-MAKING WAS
EXPRESSED BEAUTIFULLY THIS LAST
OCTOBER WHEN SHE PLACED A VERY
SPECIAL CARD THAT SHE HAD MADE
INTO THE CASKET WITH HER
GRANDPA, WHO ALSO JUST RECENTLY
DIED OF A TRAGIC ACCIDENT.
EMILIE WAS A MENTOR TO HER TWO
LITTLE SISTERS IN DELIGHTING IN
TEACHING THEM HOW TO READ, DANCE
AND FIND THE SIMPLE JOYS IN
LIFE.
EMILIE'S LAUGHTER WAS INFECTIOUS
AND ALL THOSE WHO HAD THE
PLEASURE TO MEET HER WOULD AGREE
THAT THIS WORLD IS A BETTER
PLACE BECAUSE SHE HAS BEEN IN IT
SHE WAS THEIR BEST FRIEND.
THEY WERE BORN WITHIN THREE
YEARS OF EACH OTHER, SO BY LAW,
THEY'RE VERY CLOSE.
SHE WAS TEACHING MY MIDDLE
DAUGHTER TO READ.
SHE WOULD HELP MY YOUNGEST
DAUGHTER LEARN HOW TO MAKE
THINGS, SHOW HER HOW TO DO
CRAFTS.
THEY LOOKED UP TO HER.
AND THEY LOOKED TO HER WHEN,
WHEN THEY NEEDED COMFORT.
USUALLY THAT'S, THAT IS SAVED
FOR A MOM OR A DAD.
BUT IT WAS SWEET TO SEE THE
TIMES WHEN ONE OF THEM OR FALL
OR GET THEIR FEELINGS HURT, HOW
THEY WOULD RUN TO EMILIE TO GET
SUPPORT AND HUGS AND KISSES.
SHE WAS THE TYPE OF PERSON THAT
COULD JUST LIGHT UP A ROOM.
SHE, SHE ALWAYS HAD SOMETHING
KIND TO SAY ABOUT ANYBODY.
AND HER, HER LOVE AND THE
STRENGTH THAT SHE GAVE US AND
THE EXAMPLE THAT SHE SHOWED US
IS REMARKABLE.
SHE IS AN INCREDIBLE PERSON.
AND I'M SO BLESSED TO BE HER
DAD.
I WAS LEAVING TO WORK AND SHE
WOKE UP BEFORE I LEFT.
AND I'VE ACTUALLY BEEN TEACHING
HER PORTUGUESE.
SO OUR LAST CONVERSATION WAS IN
PORTUGUESE.
SHE TOLD ME GOOD MORNING.
AND ASKED HOW I WAS DOING AND I
SAID THAT I WAS DOING WELL AND
SHE SAID THAT SHE LOVED ME AND I
GAVE HER A KISS AND I WAS OUT
THE DOOR.
FREE AGENCY IS GIVEN TO ALL OF
US TO ACT AND CHOOSE TO DO
WHATEVER WE WANT AND GOD CAN'T
TAKE THAT AWAY FROM US.
AND I KNOW THAT THAT'S SOMETHING
THAT HE WAS GIVEN AND THAT'S
WHAT HE CHOSE TO DO WITH IT.
AND I KNOW THAT GOD CAN'T TAKE
THAT AWAY.
I'M NOT MAD.
BECAUSE I HAVE MY AGENCY TO MAKE
SURE THAT I USE THIS EVENT TO DO
WHAT I CAN, TO DO WHATEVER I
CAN.
TO WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT MY
FAMILY AND MY WIFE AND MY
DAUGHTERS ARE TAKEN CARE OF.
AND THAT IF THERE'S ANYTHING
THATKY DO TO HELP ANYBODY AT ANY
TIME, ANYWHERE, THAT I WOULD BE
WILLING TO DO THAT.
AS WE MOVE ON FROM WHAT HAPPENED
HERE, WHAT HAPPENED TO SO MANY
PEOPLE, LET IT NOT TURN INTO
SOMETHING THAT DEFINES US.
BUT SOMETHING THAT INSPIRES US
TO BE BETTER, TO BE MORE
COMPASSIONATE AND MORE HUMBLE
PEOPLE.
>> EMILIE AND HER FAMILY MOVED
HER TO NEWTOWN FROM UTAH EARLIER
THIS YEAR AND SHE WILL BE LAID
TO REST IN UTAH.
YOU KNOW, THIS SHOOTING AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY IS RAISING LOTS
OF QUESTIONS, INCLUDING HOW FAR
THE SECOND AMENDMENT EXTENDS THE
RIGHTS TO BEAR ARMS.
WE'LL TAKE A CLOSER LOOK AFTER
THE BREAK.
PEOPLE HAVE DOUBTS
ABOUT TAKING ASPIRIN FOR PAIN.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
WE DON'T LET FREQUENT HEARTBURN
COME BETWEEN US
AND WHAT WE LOVE.
SO IF YOU'RE ONE OF THEM PEOPLE
WHO GETS HEARTBURN
AND THEN TREATS DAY AFTER DAY...
BLOCK THE ACID WITH PRILOSEC OTC
AND DON'T GET HEARTBURN
IN THE FIRST PLACE!
[ Male Announcer ]
ONE PILL EACH MORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBURN.
>>> THE SHOOTING HERE IN NEWTOWN
IS REVIVING DEBATE OVER GUN
CONTROL AND THE SECOND AMENDMENT
TO THE CONSTITUTION.
MOST PEOPLE THINK THEY KNOW WHAT
IT SAYS.
THAT IT JUST SAYS, YOU HAVE THE
RIGHT TO BEAR ARMS.
HERE IS THE ACTUAL TEXT.
IT SAYS A WELL-REGULATED
MILITIA, BEING NECESSARY TO THE
SECURITY OF A FREE STATE, THE
RIGHT OF THE PEOPLE TO KEEP AND
BEAR ARMS, SHALL NOT BE
INFRINGED.
DEB, THAT'S THE ACTUAL TEXT
THERE.
>> THAT'S IT.
AND THAT'S WHY WHEN YOU HEAR
PEOPLE TALK ABOUT GUN CONTROL.
THEY SAY WE RESPECT THE SECOND
AMENDMENT BUT WHEN IT COMES TO
THE MORE MILITARY WEAPONS,
THAT'S WHERE IT GETS A LITTLE
BIT TRICKIER.
THE TRAGEDY WILL ONCE AGAIN FUEL
THE DEBATE OVER A RIGHT TO BEAR
ARMS, HOW MUCH REGULATION SHOULD
THERE BE, REGARDING THE
ACCESSIBILITY OF GUNS.
WE WANT TO BRING IN OUR CNN
CONTRIBUTOR, FORMER FBI
ASSISTANT DIRECTOR, TOM FUENTES.
TOM, NO ONE IS TALKING ABOUT
REMOVING THE RIGHT TO BEAR ARMS.
BUT THERE ARE 310 MILLION
NONMILITARY WEAPONS IN THE
UNITED STATES, THAT IS MORE THAN
ONE FOR EVERY SINGLE AMERICAN.
FIRST OF ALL, IS IT EVEN
POSSIBLE TO TRY TO LIMIT THE
WEAPONS THAT ARE OUT THERE.
HOW DO YOU EVEN DO THAT?
>> HI, DEBRA.
IT WOULD BE POSSIBLE.
IT WOULD BE, HAVE TO BE DONE
OVER A LONG PERIOD OF TIME.
BUT WHEN YOU LOOK AT THE RIGHT
TO BEAR ARMS, YOU KNOW, WE'RE
REALLY LOOKING AT AN ISSUE
THAT'S ON THE CONTINUUM.
WHERE YOU MIGHT HAVE A
SINGLE-SHOT PISTOL ON THE ONE
END OF THE CONTINUUM AND NUCLEAR
WEAPONS ON THE OTHER.
THE RIGHT OF A CITIZEN TO
POSSESS ARMS, DOES THAT MEAN
THEY CAN GO OUT AND OBTAIN
NUCLEAR WEAPONS AND AUTOMATIC
WEAPONS AND TANKS AND FIREPOWER,
AIRCRAFT CARRIERS?
NO.
THE GOVERNMENT SAYS THAT AT SOME
POINT, WE'RE GOING TO CUT YOU
OFF AND YOU CAN'T HAVE A MOUR
POWERFUL WEAPON THAN WHAT THE
GOVERNMENT SAYS.
BUT THE ARGUMENT NOW IS AT WHAT
POINT ON THE CONTINUUM TO DO WE
MAKE THE LIMITATION, DO WE SAY
YOU CAN HAVE PISTOLS, SHOTGUNS
AND SINGLE-SHOT RIFLES, YOU
CANNOT HAVE AN ASSAULT RIFLE, A
FULLY AUTOMATIC WEAPON.
WE'RE REALLY DEBATING AT WHAT
POINT DO WE SAY ENOUGH IS
ENOUGH.
YOU DON'T NEED TO HAVE FIREPOWER
BEYOND THE CERTAIN POINT ON THE
CONTINUUM.
ANOTHER POINT CONSTITUTIONALLY
FOR ME IS WHEN SECOND AMEND M
WAS PASSED AS PART OF THE BILL
OF RIGHTS, YOU DIDN'T HAVE A LOT
OF DIFFERENCE BETWEEN THE
FIREPOWER OF A MILITIA AND LOCAL
FARMERS WITH THEIR MUSKETS AND
LET'S SAY THE U.S. GOVERNMENT AT
THE TIME OR THE BRITISH
GOVERNMENT BEFORE THEM.
WHO HAD BASICALLY MUSKETS AND
CANNONS AND NOT MUCH MORE THAN
THAT.
AGAIN, THE ABILITY OF THE
POPULATION TO HAVE SOME KIND OF
A PARODY TO FEND OFF TYRANNY,
THEY WOULDN'T BE ABLE TO DO IT.
EVEN AS WE WON THE REVOLUTIONARY
WAR WITH MUSKETS AND CANNONS.
BUT TODAY, ARE THE CITIZENS
GOING TO PREVENT THE TYRANNY OF
THE UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT
WITH EVEN THIS BUSHMASTER OR
THESE PISTOLS WHEN THE
GOVERNMENT HAS GOT NUKES?
I DON'T THINK SO.
TIMES HAVE CHANGED IN 250 YEARS
AND IT REALLY IS TIME TO MIKE AN
ASSESSMENT OF WHAT IS REASONABLE
UNDER THE SECOND AMENDMENT FOR
PEOPLE TO BE ABLE TO PROTECT
THEMSELVES.
BUT NOT HAVE SUCH A
PROLIFERATION OF WEAPONS THAT
THEY REPEATEDLY FALL IN THE
HANDS OF MENTALLY DISTURBED
PEOPLE WHO COMMIT THESE ACTS,
WITH FAR TOO MUCH FREQUENCY ANY
MORE.
>> AS WERE YOU SAYING THAT, TOM,
YOU TOOK THE WORDS RIGHT OUT OF
MY MOUTH.
THAT WAS IN THE CONSTITUTION,
WHEN THEY PUT THAT IN THE
CONSTITUTION.
MUSKETS, PEA SHOOTERS, NO ONE
THOUGHT ABOUT ALL OF THESE GUNS.
THEY PROBABLY HAD NO IDEA WHAT
THESE EXTENDED MAGAZINES, THAT
KILL PEOPLE AT RANDOM.
JUST A MATTER OF MOMENTS.
AND SO REALLYI THE
INTERPRETATION OF THAT.
IT SEEMS, JUST LOOKING AT IT,
COMMON SENSIC ALABAE IICALLSENS.
PEOPLE SHOULD HAVE A WAY TO RISE
UP AGAINST THE GOVERNMENT.
NOT JUST GO OUT AND HUNT PEOPLE
DOWN BECAUSE YOU CAN GET A
WEAPON.
>> AND IT'S NOT GOING TO HAPPEN
ANY MORE.
IF YOU HAVE A LOCAL MILITIA THAT
SAYS, AND WE'VE HAD SOME, AS THE
FBI HAS HAD MANY CASES OF THIS.
IF YOU HAVE A LOCAL MILITIA
THAT'S DECIDED TO TAKE ON THE
UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT.
WOULDN'T EVEN BE ABLE TO TAKE ON
A SMALL CONTINGENT OF NAVY
S.E.A.L.s, MUCH LESS THE REST OF
THE GOVERNMENT WITH NUCLEAR
WEAPONS AND STEALTH FIGHTERS AND
BOMBERS AND CRUISE MISSILES, THE
ARRAY OF WEAPONRY THAT THIS
GOVERNMENT POSSESSES AND MOST
DEVELOPED GOVERNMENTS POSSESS,
THERE'S TO WAY ANY GROUP OF
CITIZENS CAN PUT TOGETHER ENOUGH
OF THEIR BUSHMASTERS AND GLOCKS
AND SIG SAUERS TO TAKE ON A
GOVERNMENT ANY MORE.
>> TOM FUENTES, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
>> THANK YOU, DON.
>>> IN TIMES OF TRAGEDY,
REMEMBERING MOMENTS OF GOODNESS.
AS A NATION GRIEVES, WE'RE GOING
TO LOOK AT STORIES OF
INSPIRATION.
HEY SIS,
IT'S SO GREAT
TO SEE YOU.
YOU, TOO!
OH, CLOUDY GLASSES.
YOU DIDN'T
HAVE TO COME OVER!
ACTUALLY, HONEY,
I THINK I DID...
OH? YOU DID?
WHOA, LADIES, EASY.
HI.
CASCADE KITCHEN COUNSELOR.
WE CAN HELP AVOID THIS
WITH CASCADE COMPLETE PACS.
SEE, OVER TIME,
CASCADE COMPLETE PACS
FIGHT FILM BUILDUP TWO TIMES
BETTER THAN FINISH QUANTUM.
TO HELP LEAVE GLASSES SPARKLING
SHINY!
TOO BAD IT DOESN'T WORK
ON WINDOWS.
OKAY, I'M OUTTA HERE.
CASCADE. THE CLEAR CHOICE.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
[ Woman ]
♪ WHAT I WANT THIS SEASON
♪ IF YOU'D LIKE
TO TRY AND GUESS ♪
♪ IT IS SOMETHING VERY SPECIAL
♪ I WOULD READILY CONFESS
[ dogs barking ]
♪ 'CAUSE ALL I WANT
THIS SEASON ♪
♪ IS SOMETHING FROM YOUR HEART
♪ LA DA DA, LA DA DA
[ Male Announcer ] THINKING
OF OTHERS THIS HOLIDAY SEASON,
TRAVELERS.
>>> WE WANTED TO END THIS HOUR
WITH A REMINDER AN IMPORTANT
REMINDER, AFTER ALL WE'VE SEEN
THIS WEEKEND.
THAT PEOPLE CAN BE GOOD IN ACTS
OF KINDNESS ARE EVERYWHERE.
WE WANT TO YOU REMEMBER THIS --
JUST LAST MONTH, THIS NEW YORK
CITY POLICE OFFICER MADE NEWS BY
OFFERING A HOMELESS MAN IN TIMES
SQUARE A PAIR OF BOOTS ON A COLD
NIGHT.
OR THIS -- A TENNESSEE BOY WHO
HELPED HIS BROTHER IN A
WHEELCHAIR COMPETE IN A
TRIATHLON, HELPING HIM ACHIEVE
HIS DREAM TO CROSS A FINISH
LINE.
>>> OR THE FOOTBALL TEAM AT ONE
ARIZONA HIGH SCHOOL WHO
PROTECTED THIS FRESH HAN WITH
SPECIAL NEEDS FROM BULLIES.
AND JUST THIS WEEKEND, THERE'S A
TEXAS COP WHO WRAPPED $100 BILL
IN A TRAFFIC TICKET HE GAVE TO
ONE STRUGGLING DAD.
JUST ONE OF THE ENCOURAGING
MOMENTS OF HUMANITY WE HAVE SEEN
THIS YEAR.
IT'S IMPORTANT TO KEEP IN MIND
THERE'S STILL GOOD IN THE WORLD
EVEN WHEN TRAGIC THINGS HAPPEN.
>>> WHAT COULD PROMPT ONE TO
CARRY OUT SUCH HORRIFIC ACTS,
MANY QUESTIONS WILL NEVER BE
ANSWERED.
WE'LL TALK WITH AN EXPERT IN
CRIMINAL BEHAVIOR.
ERIN BURNETT JOINS US, NEXT.
SEN.
I HAVE A COLD,
AND I TOOK NYQUIL,
BUT I'M STILL "STUBBED" UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT DOESN'T HAVE A DECONGESTANT.
NO WAY.
[ Male Announcer ] SORRY.
Alka-Seltzer Plus FIGHTS
YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A FAST ACTING
DECONGESTANT
TO RELIEVE YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
[ sighs ] THANKS!
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus.
♪ OH
WHAT A RELIEF IT IS! ♪
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
AND SAVE $1
VISIT Alka-Seltzer ON FACEBOOK.
he opened up
Jake's very private world.
At first, Jake's family
thought they saved Ziggy,
but his connection with Jake
has been a lifesaver.
For a love this strong,
his family only feeds him Iams.
Compared to other
leading brands,
it has 50% more
animal protein...
...to help keep Ziggy's body
as strong as a love
that reaches further
than anyone's words.
Iams. Keep Love Strong.