PARKING LOT WAS FULL, WOLF, WE
SAW FAMILIES GOING IN.
WE DIDN'T FILM THEM, OBVIOUSLY
FOR PRIVACY.
BUT PSYCHOLOGISTS,
PSYCHIATRISTS, CHILD COUNSELORS.
ONE OF THE THINGS PEOPLE WERE
TELLING US WAS THAT THIS IDEA
THAT THE COMMUNITY ITSELF COULD
BE A SOURCE OF HEALING.
JUST SIMPLY KNOWING THAT PEOPLE
WERE SEEKING COUNSELING AND WERE
ALL GOING THROUGH IT TOGETHER
ALSO PROVIDED A LOT OF COMFORT
TO THESE PEOPLE.
SO I THINK THAT IS WHY THEY
DECIDED TO DO THIS HERE.
>> SANJAY, STAY WITH ME, DON'T
GO AWAY HERE.
AN UNIMAGINABLE TRAGEDY, GROWING
EVEN MORE HORRIFYING WITH EVERY
GRUESOME NEW DETAIL WE LEARN.
>> EVERYBODY, DEATH WAS CAUSED
BY -- EVERYONE WE HAVE COMPLETED
SO FAR WAS CAUSED BY GUNSHOT
WOUNDS.
AND OBVIOUSLY, THE MANNER OF
DEATH ON ALL OF THESE CASES HAS
BEEN CLASSIFIED AS HOMICIDE.
>> A LONG TIME MEDICAL EXAMINER
CALLS IT PROBABLY THE WORST
THING HE HAS EVER SEEN IN MORE
THAN 30 YEARS IN THIS FIELD.
MOST EVERYBODY HIT MORE THAN
ONCE.
EACH WITH A SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE,
AND THIS.
>> WHEN I SAW THOSE TEACHERS AND
I LOCKED EYES WITH EACH OF THEM
SEPARATELY, WHEN I FOUND THE TWO
CHILDREN IF I COULD GO BACK I
WOULD -- I WOULD EMBRACE THEM.
BECAUSE I HAD NO IDEA WHAT THEY
HAD GONE THROUGH.
>> THE PARENTS OF CHILDREN WHO
SURVIVED THE SHOOTING STRUGGLE
TO COME TO TERMS WITH WHAT THEIR
CHILDREN AND THE TEACHERS HAD TO
ENDURE AS WE LEARN THE NAMES OF
ALL 26 PEOPLE KILLED.
NOT ONE OF THOSE 20 CHILDREN WHO
DIED OVER THE AGE OF SEVEN YEARS
OLD.
THEY WERE SIX AND SEVEN YEARS
OLD, ALL FIRST GRADERS.
WE WANT TO WELCOME OUR VIEWERS
IN THE UNITED STATES AND AROUND
THE WORLD.
I'M WOLF BLITZER, REPORTING HERE
FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
LET'S BRING IN OUR NATIONAL
CORRESPONDENT, SUSAN CANDIOTTI.
SHE IS JOINING US WITH MORE
INFORMATION, THE VERY LATEST ON
THE INVESTIGATION, WHAT ARE YOU
LEARNING, SUSAN?
>> Reporter: HI, WOLF, WE'RE NOT
GOING TO DWELL ON THE SHOOTER'S
NAME, BUT HE IS TWENTY-YEAR-OLD
ADAM LANZA, AND WE'RE LEARNING
TODAY MORE ON HOW VICIOUS THE
ATTACKS WERE.
THIS INFORMATION COMING TO US
FROM THE CHIEF MEDICAL EXAMINER.
>> ALL THE WOUNDS THAT I KNOW OF
AT THIS POINT WERE CAUSED BY THE
WEAPON.
I ONLY DID SEVEN OF THE
AUTOPSIES.
THE VICTIMS I HAD RANGED FROM
THREE TO ELEVEN, AND I ONLY SAW
TWO OF THEM WITH CLOSE RANGE
SHOOTING.
THIS IS A SAMPLE, I REALLY DON'T
HAVE MORE INFORMATION.
THE BULLETS ARE DESIGNED IN SUCH
A FASHION THAT THE ENERGY --
THIS IS VERY CLINICAL, I
SHOULDN'T BE SAYING THIS.
BUT THE ENERGY DEPOSITED IN THE
TISSUE, SO THE BULLET STAYS IN.
>> Reporter: NOW THE LONG WEAPON
THAT THE CHIEF MEDICAL EXAMINER
REFERRED TO IS ONE OF THE THREE
GUNS THAT OUR SOURCES TELL US
WERE FOUND NEXT TO THE SHOOTER
IN THE CLASSROOM.
YOU'LL REMEMBER THOSE THREE, TWO
OF THEM HANDGUNS, AND THE THIRD
A LONGGUN, THAT WE HAVE COME TO
KNOW AS A SEMIAUTOMATIC CALLED A
BUSHWHACKER, NOW -- I'M SORRY --
I UNDERSTAND THERE MAY BE A
TECHNICAL PROBLEM.
>> SUSAN I'M GOING TO INTERRUPT
YOU FOR A MOMENT.
BECAUSE THE BROTHER OF NANCY
LANZA, THE MOTHER OF THE
SHOOTER, THE BROTHER, JAMES
CHAMPION IS SPEAKING NOW IN NEW
HAMPSHIRE.
HE IS A POLICE OFFICER.
>> IS INVOLVED IN, IS GOING TO
GO THROUGH THE COUNNNECTICUT STE
POLICE, AND THE LOCAL POLICE.
SO YOU WON'T HAVE ANY
INFORMATION COMING FROM ANY
DEPARTMENT IN THIS COUNTY ABOUT
WHAT THEY'RE DOING ON BEHALF OF
CONNECTICUT.
I CAN -- THINK I CAN SAY THAT
LAW ENFORCEMENT HERE IS
RESPONDING TO ANY REQUESTS THAT
CONNECTICUT COULD MAKE.
AND WE WILL DO ANYTHING THAT IS
ASKED OF US TO ASSIST ON THAT.
THE ROCKINGHAM COUNTY SHERIFF,
MIKE DOWNING IS HERE WITH ME.
HE HAS A STATEMENT FROM THE
CHAMPION FAMILY HE WOULD LIKE TO
READ.
AND WE -- AFTER THAT, I GUESS WE
CAN TRY AND ANSWER QUESTIONS,
ALTHOUGH WE'RE NOT GOING TO BE
ANSWERING QUESTIONS ABOUT THE
INVESTIGATION IN GENERAL.
SO I'LL TURN IT OVER TO SHERIFF
DOWNING.
>> THANK YOU, GOOD EVENING.
MY NAME --
>> JAMES CHAMPION, BY THE WAY,
IS THE BROTHER OF NANCY LANZA,
HE WAS GOING TO MAKE A
STATEMENT.
BUT HE DECIDED HE COULDN'T
BECAUSE IT IS TOO EMOTIONAL.
WE'RE HEARING NOW FROM HIS
COLLEAGUES.
HE IS A POLICE OFFICER.
>> THE FAMILY OF NANCY LANZA
SHARE THE GRIEF OF A COMMUNITY
AND NATION AS WE STRUGGLE TO
COMPREHEND THE TREMENDOUS LOSS
THAT WE ALL SHARE.
OUR HEARTS AND PRAYERS ARE WITH
THOSE WHO SHARE IN THIS LOSS.
THE FAMILY, TEACHERS, STAFF AND
THE STUDENTS OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, THE FIRST
RESPONDERS AND TO ALL OF US
TOUCHED BY THIS TRAGEDY.
ON BEHALF OF NANCY'S MOTHER AND
SIBLINGS WE REACH OUT TO THE
COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN AND EXPRESS
OUR HEARTFELT SORROW FOR THE
LOSS OF INNOCENCE THAT HAS
AFFECTED SO MANY.
THE FAMILY REQUESTS THAT YOU
RESPECT THEIR PRIVACY DURING
THEIR TIME OF ANGUISH AND LOSS.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> ARE THERE ANY QUESTIONS --
LIKE I SAID, THERE IS NOT AN
AWFUL LOT WE CAN ANSWER.
>> WHO CALLED THE FBI AND OTHER
AUTHORITIES --
>> THE ONLY THING I CAN TELL YOU
IS THAT LAW ENFORCEMENT,
GENERALLY, HAS OBVIOUSLY
VOLUNTEERED ANY ASSISTANCE TO
CONNECTICUT.
AND ARE RESPONDING TO ANY
REQUESTS THAT COME OUT OF
CONNECTICUT.
THE REQUESTS THAT THEY'RE MAKING
OF US AND OUR RESPONSE BACK TO
THEM WILL GO THROUGH THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE, AND WE
WON'T HAVE ANY COMMENTS ABOUT
THAT.
OTHER THAN WE'LL DO ANYTHING WE
CAN TO HELP.
>> CAN YOU MAYBE TALK A LITTLE
BIT ABOUT HER, WHAT SHE IS
LIKE --
>> THIS IS CHIEF DONALD BRIGGS
HEN
HERE.
>> VERY, VERY KIND, CONSIDERATE,
LOVING YOUNG LADY.
SHE LIVED HERE A GOOD PART OF
HER LIFE.
SHE WAS VERY INVOLVED IN THE
COMMUNITY.
VERY WELL RESPECTED.
>> CHIEF, CAN YOU TALK ABOUT THE
CHAMPIONS IN GENERAL, WELL KNOWN
IN TOWN?
>> I CAN TELL YOU, SMALL TOWN,
THAT MRS. CHAMPION, DOTTIE,
WORKED AS A SCHOOL NURSE AT THE
SCHOOL FOR A NUMBER OF YEARS.
A WONDERFUL PERSON, VERY GOOD
WITH CHILDREN.
JIM CHAMPION WORKED FOR ME FOR A
NUMBER OF YEARS AS THE CAPTAIN
OF THE POLICE DEPARTMENT.
AND HE CURRENTLY WORKS FOR ME AS
A PART-TIME OFFICER AS WELL AS
FOR SHERIFF DOWNING AS A DEPUTY.
>> HAVE YOU SPOKEN MUCH TO HIM
SINCE HE HAS HEARD THIS NEWS?
CAN YOU TELL US ANYTHING ABOUT
HOW HE IS DOING?
>> THE WHOLE FAMILY IS TRAU
TRAUMATIZED BY THIS EVENT, VERY
SAD, VERY SAD.
>> DO YOU KNOW IF HE WAS IN
CONTACT, HAS HE EXPRESSED
ANYTHING -- ANYTHING --
>> I'M SORRY I DIDN'T HEAR.
I HAVE NOT.
>> CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT --
>> HE HAS NOT.
>> WHAT DOES HE SAY ABOUT --
THIS DAY.
>> I HAVE NOT HAD A CONVERSATION
WITH HIM.
>> DO YOU KNOW HOW CLOSE HE WAS
TO NANCY AND HER SONS?
>> VERY CLOSE.
>> WHEN IS THE LAST TIME THEY
WERE BACK HERE --
>> I ACTUALLY SAW HER LAST
NOVEMBER WHEN JIM CHAMPION
RETIRED.
I SAW HER AT THE RETIREMENT
PARTY.
I HAVEN'T SEEN THE CHILDREN
FOR -- SINCE THEY LEFT HERE IN
1998.
>> YOU SAID --
>> MY UNDERSTANDING IT WAS 1998,
THAT WAS MY UNDERSTANDING.
>> ANY OTHER QUESTIONS?
>> OKAY, THANKS A LOT.
>> ALL RIGHT, SO LET ME JUST PUT
IN PERSPECTIVE WHAT WE HAVE JUST
HEARD, AND SANJAY GUPTA IS STILL
WITH US, AS WELL.
JAMES CHAMPION, SANJAY IS A
POLICE OFFICER IN KINGSTON, NEW
HAMPSHIRE.
HE WAS GOING TO BE MAKING A
STATEMENT RIGHT NOW.
HIS SISTER WAS KILLED YESTERDAY.
NANCY LANZA, THE MOTHER OF ADAM
LANZA, THE MAN WHO WENT IN, THE
TWENTY-YEAR-OLD, AND KILLED ALL
OF THESE PEOPLE HERE IN NEWTOWN
WHERE WE ARE.
HE IS TOO EMOTIONAL.
HIS SISTER IS DEAD.
HE IS THE UNCLE OF THIS YOUNG
MAN.
BUT OTHER POLICE OFFICERS AND
THE DISTRICT ATTORNEY CAME OUT
AND SPOKE ON HIS BEHALF.
WANTING TO SAYHAT THEY WILL
OBVIOUSLY COOPERATE FULLY WITH
THIS INVESTIGATION.
YOU THINK OF THE ENORMITY,
THOUGH, HERE HE IS A POLICE
OFFICER IN NEW HAMPSHIRE.
HIS SISTER IS DEAD, HIS NEPHEW
IS DEAD, KILLS HIMSELF AFTER
KILLING ALL OF THESE YOUNG
PEOPLE, AND SIX ADULTS.
I CAN ONLY MAN WHAT HE CAN BE
GOING THROUGH.
>> AND IT SEEMED LIKE HE WANTED
TO COME OUT AND TALK ABOUT IT.
CERTAINLY ALL THIS INFORMATION.
THAT WAS WHAT THE PRESS
CONFERENCE WAS ABOUT.
AND AT THE LAST MOMENT, HE WAS
TOO OVERCOME TO DO IT.
WHICH IS NOT SURPRISING, GIVEN
THE LOSS.
WE TALKED ABOUT THE PEOPLE WHO
DIED IN THE SCHOOL, BUT THE
LANZA FAMILY, THE CHAMPION
FAMILY, WHICH IS LANZA'S BROTHER
IN THE CASE, THEY'RE OBVIOUSLY
TRYING TO COME TO TERMS WITH
THIS, AS WELL.
INCOMPRENHENSIBLE IS THE WAY
THEY DESCRIBED IT.
THERE WILL BE ANSWERS, BUT I'M
JUST NOT SURE, WE STILL HAVE NOT
HEARD FROM THEM, IT IS
INCOMPREHENSIBLE, THE BIG
QUESTION REMAINS, WE MAY NEVER
FULLY GET THE ANSWER WHY.
>> Reporter: BUT PEOPLE ARE
ASKING THAT QUESTION, WOLF.
YOU JUST HEARD THAT QUESTION
FROM THE STATEMENT -- ON BEHALF
OF THE LANZA FAMILY.
AND ALL DAY WE HAVE BEEN
GATHERING MORE AND MORE
INFORMATION ABOUT THE SUSPECT
AND HIS FAMILY, ALI, YOU HAVE
BEEN DIGGING INTO THIS.
WE JUST HEARD FROM FAMILY
MEMBERS OF NANCY LANZA.
WHAT ARE YOU LEARNING ABOUT
NANCY?
BECAUSE SHE IS ALSO A VICTIM IN
THIS CRIME?
>> Reporter: YES, SHE IS
ABSOLUTELY A VICTIM, WE'RE ABOUT
TWO AND A HALF MILES AWAY FROM
THE QUIET AREA WHERE NANCY LIVED
WITH HER SON.
BEYOND THE POLICE CAR, YOU CAN'T
SEE AROUND THE AREA.
THE LANZAS MOVED INTO THIS AREA
IN 1997 OR 8, THEY PURCHASED
HOUSE IN 1998.
THEY LIVED IN THE HOUSE TOGETHER
UNTIL NANCY AND HER HUSBAND,
PETER, SEPARATED SEVERAL YEARS
AGO AND DIVORCED IN 2009.
AND THAT LEFT RYAN, THE SON WHO
NOW LIVES IN HOBOKEN, NEW
JERSEY, AND IT LEFT NANCY AND
ADAM LIVING IN THE HOUSE.
NANCY WORKED IN FINANCE IN
BOSTON, AND HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
SHE RECENTLY STOPPED WORKING,
WHICH IS INTERESTING.
WE DON'T KNOW WHETHER SHE WAS
RETIRING FROM WORKING OR
SPENDING TIME AT HOME.
BUT SHE DID SEEM TO CONFIDE WITH
FRIENDS THAT SHE WANTED TO TAKE
CARE OF ADAM.
SO THEY LIVED IN THIS HOUSE
UNTIL FRIDAY MORNING.
AND WE SPOKE TO RESIDENTS AROUND
HERE.
IT IS A VERY QUIET NEIGHBORHOOD.
ALL THE LIGHTS ARE FROM CAMERAS.
BIG HOUSES, WE SPOKE TO ONE
NEIGHBOR WHO SAID THEY SEEMED
QUITE NORMAL, LISTEN.
>> THEY WERE A QUIET, SEEMINGLY
FRIENDLY PEOPLE, I DON'T THINK
PEOPLE IN THIS NEIGHBORHOOD
REALLY KNEW THEM TOO WELL.
>> Reporter: WE ALSO SPOKE --
THAT IS A YOUNG MAN WHOSE MOTHER
WE ALSO SPOKE TO SAID LOOK,
NANCY WAS INTO GARDENING.
SHE HAD -- YOU KNOW, THEY WERE
NOT ALL THAT SOCIAL WITH THEIR
NEIGHBORS, BUT THEY DIDN'T KNOW
IF THEY HAD A SOCIAL CIRCLE
OUTSIDE OF HERE.
AND THAT IS THE STORY, NOT A LOT
OF INFORMATION.
THIS AREA, THEY ASKED RESIDENTS
TO LEAVE, SOME HAD COME BACK.
IT IS AN ACTIVE CRIME SCENE,
POLICE SAY THEY'RE FINDING A
GREAT DEAL OF INFORMATION FROM
THE SHOOTING SCENE AT THE HOUSE.
BUT A LOT OF NEIGHBORS ARE NOT
REALLY TALKING ABOUT WHAT IS
GOING ON.
THERE IS SOME CONFUSION.
THIS IS A STORY WHERE THERE ARE
A LOT OF CONFLICTING DETAILS ALL
OVER THE PLACE.
ONE AREA IS THE GUNS, WHERE THEY
CAME FROM, WHAT THEY WERE USED
FOR.
NANCY LANZA APPARENTLY TOLD A
DECORATOR, WHO HAD DONE THE
CHRISTMAS DECORATIONS ON THEIR
HOUSE, THAT NANCY SAID SHE
APPARENTLY SHOWED HIM A GUN, A
RIFLE THAT SHE HAD RECENTLY
BOUGHT AND SAID SHE LIKED TO
TAKE HER KIDS FOR TARGET
SHOOTING.
THE ATF LOOKED AT RANGES IN THE
AREA, AND SAID THEY DON'T HAVE
EVIDENCE THAT THE FAMILY WENT TO
LOCAL SHOOTING RANGES TO SHOOT.
BUT THAT IS THE LATEST
INFORMATION.
>> Reporter: IT WAS SURPRISING
TO SOME, ALI, THAT THE
INFORMATION CAME OUT THAT THE
GUNS, WHILE THE NUMBER OF GUNS
AND HOW MANY GUNS WERE ON ADAM
LANZA AT THE TIME OF THE
SHOOTING AT THE SCHOOL, IT WAS
SURPRISING TO MANY THAT THE GUNS
WERE LEGALLY PURCHASED BY NANCY
LANZA.
>> Reporter: YOU DO HAVE TO DO
CERTAIN THINGS, INCLUDING TAKE A
COURSE WITH THE GUN LAWS.
OF THE SIX GUNS WE HEARD WERE IN
THE HOUSE, THREE OF THEM WERE
STANDARD RIFLES.
AND THE THREE HE TOOK WITH HIM
WERE SEMIAUTOMATICS, IN WHICH
CASE YOU CAN PULL WITH TRIGGER
PULLS.
THEY MAKE THE MOST SENSE OF
ASSAULT WEAPONS.
THEY'RE NOT CALLED ASSAULT
WEAPONS, THAT IS A DIFFERENT
CATEGORY OF GUNS.
BUT IT DOES SEEM HE HAD ACCESS
TO GUNS THAT WERE NOT REGISTERED
TO HIM.
THEY WERE REGISTERED TO NANCY,
THAT IS PARTLY BECAUSE
CONNECTICUT KEEPS SUCH GOOD GUN
LAWS THAT WE WERE ABLE TO FIND
THAT OUT QUICKLY.
>> ALL RIGHT, THANK YOU, GREAT
REPORTING, WOLF I'M GOING TO GO
BACK TO YOU.
MANY QUESTIONS REMAIN.
AS YOU SAID SO MANY TIMES, THE
QUESTION WHY?
IT DOESN'T LOOK LIKE IT IS EVER
GOING TO BE ANSWERED.
>> YEAH, AT LEAST NOT COMPLETELY
TO BE SURE.
KATE, THANK YOU.
WE'RE BEGINNING ALSO TO PUT
NAMES AND FACES WITH SOME OF
THOSE WHO LOST THEIR LIVES IN
THIS TRULY UNSPEAKABLE TRAGEDY.
ALL SIX OF THE ADULTS WHO DIED
AT THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL WERE WOMEN.
HERE ARE SOME OF THEIR STORIES.
VICTORIA SOTO'S FAMILY SAID SHE
HAD HER STUDENTS HIDDEN BEHIND
HER TRYING TO PROTECT THEM WHEN
SHE WAS SHOT AND KILLED AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
HER COUSIN SAYS THE HARDEST PART
WAS WAITING TO HEAR WHETHER SHE
HAD SURVIVED OR NOT.
>> AND AT THAT POINT, IT WAS THE
HARDEST FOR THE WHOLE FAMILY,
JUST A WAITING GAME TO RECEIVE
WORD ON WHAT HAPPENED TO VICKY'S
CLASS.
>> ALSO KILLED, LAUREN RUSSO,
HIRED JUST LAST MONTH AS A
SUBSTITUTE TEACHER.
HER FAMILY SAYS SHE ALWAYS
WANTED TO BE A TEACHER SINCE
BEFORE SHE EVEN WENT TO
KINDERGARTEN.
SHE HAS TWO DAUGHTERS IN THEIR
TWENTIES, MARRIED 31 YEARS AND
GOES TO A LAKE HOUSE WITH HER
HUSBAND, IN UPSTATE, NEW YORK.
AND THE PRINCIPAL, SERIOUS ABOUT
TEACHING.
>> SHE IS AN EXCITING, JOYFUL,
JUST AN INCREDIBLE EDUCATOR, AND
THEN TO LOSE SOMEBODY LIKE THAT
IN OUR DISTRICT, IT IS SAD.
>> SHE WAS A PERSONAL FRIEND AND
WONDERFUL LEADER.
>> Reporter: SHE HAD RECENTLY
OVERSEEN THE INSTALLATION OF A
NEW SECURITY SYSTEM, REQUIRING
EVERY VISITOR AFTER 9:30 TO GET
BUZZED IN AND SHOW ID.
>> SHE TRULY DID BELIEVE IN
CREATING AN ENVIRONMENT WHERE
CHILDREN FELT SAFE.
I REALLY FEEL THAT IS THE TRAGIC
IRONY.
>> SHE WAS ALSO A PARENT
HERSELF, RAISING TWO DAUGHTERS
AND THREE STEPDAUGHTERS.
RESIDENTS SAY HOCHSPRUNG WAS
WELL LOVED.
>> GOD BLESS HER, SHE WAS JUST A
VERY SPECIAL PERSON.
AND ALL THE PARENTS KNEW THAT.
>> Reporter: TWO OTHER WOMEN
ALSO DIED AT THE SCHOOL, RACHEL
DAVINO, ONLY TWENTY-NINE YEARS
OLD.
AND ANNE MARIE MURPHY, FIFTY-TWO
YEARS OLD.
IF YOU WOULD LIKE TO HELP IN
THIS REALLY HORRIFIC TRAGEDY,
YOU CAN DONATE TO THE SERVICES,
THE MENTAL HEALTH CLINIC WILL BE
OPEN ALL WEEKEND FROM 9:00 A.M.
UNTIL 4:00 P.M. FOR GRIEF
COUNSELING.
YOU CAN FIND ALL THE INFORMATION
ON CNN/IMPACT.
PARENTS OF CHILDREN WHO SURVIVED
THIS CHILDREN, IT IS A HORRIFIC
SHOOTING.
THEY ARE STRUGGLING RIGHT NOW TO
COME TO TERMS WITH WHAT THEY
EXPERIENCED.
YOU'RE GOING TO SEE ONE OF THOSE
WRENCHING ACCOUNTS, THAT IS JUST
AHEAD.
>> I CAN'T LOOK AT MY CHILDREN'S
FACES NOW WITHOUT SEEING THE
FACES OF EVERY ONE OF THEIR SOUL
MATES AND ALL OF THEIR FRIENDS.
AND EVERYTHING WE'RE DOING RIGHT
NOW, SAYING, TALKING ABOUT
CHRISTMAS.
AND JUST THINKING YOUR FRIENDS
SHOULD ALL BE HERE.
IT IS SO HEAVY -- SO HEAVY ON
YOUR HEART.
>>> WE'RE BACK HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
OUR SPECIAL "THE SITUATION ROOM"
COVERAGE OF THIS HORRIFIC MASS
SHOOTING CONTINUES.
26 PEOPLE GUNNED DOWN YESTERDAY,
SIX ADULTS, ALL WOMEN.
SIX AND SEVEN-YEAR-OLDS, ALL
FIRST GRADERS.
HERE TOM FOREMAN IS JOINING US
TO BREAK DOWN THE NEWEST
INFORMATION COMING IN ON HOW
THIS SHOOTING HAPPENED, TOM?
>> YOU KNOW, WOLF, IF THEY'RE
GOING TO FIGURE OUT THE WHY IN
THIS CASE, WHY IT HAPPENED,
INVESTIGATORS HOPE THEY CAN DO
IT BY RETRACING THE STEPS.
REALLY SPANNING THREE STATES.
THEY LOOKED AT THE BROTHER'S
APARTMENT HERE DOWN IN HOBOKEN,
NEW JERSEY, BY THE WAY, JUST
ACROSS FROM NEW YORK CITY.
AND UP HERE, THEY GO TO THE
MOTHER'S HOUSE, WHERE THEY FOUND
HER BODY.
AND THIS IS WHERE THEY BELIEVE
IT ALL STARTED WITH HER MURDER.
OF COURSE, THEIR BIG FOCUS IS ON
THE SCHOOL ITSELF.
LET'S MOVE OVER THERE AND TAKE A
LOOK.
BECAUSE AUTHORITIES BELIEVE THAT
AFTER KILLING HIS MOTHER,
WHETHER IMMEDIATELY, OR AFTER A
PERIOD OF TIME, WE DON'T KNOW,
THAT THE GUNMAN WENT OVER TO THE
SCHOOL AND THERE, HE HAD THESE
WEAPONS IN HIS CAR OR SOME
VERSION OF THESE WEAPONS.
AND HE BEGAN TO MOVE IN ON THE
SCHOOL ITSELF.
WE HAD A BETTER PICTURE, A CLOSE
ARE TIMELINE LOOKING AT RADIO
REPORTS AND OTHER EYEWITNESS
ACCOUNTS.
9:30 IN THE MORNING IS WHEN WE
BELIEVED HE WOULD HAVE ACTUALLY
APPROACHED THE SCHOOL ITSELF,
LEAVING, WE THINK, THIS CAR OVER
HERE.
THEY PUT A LOT OF FOCUS ON IT.
AND EVEN IF IT WERE THIS CAR, HE
WOULD HAVE COME THIS WAY, UP TO
THESE FRONT DOORS.
AND EARLIER IT WAS MENTIONED
THIS NEW SECURITY SYSTEM, THAT
PREVENTED THE FIRST BARRIER TO
HIM.
BECAUSE IT WAS LOCKED AT A TIME.
AND THERE WAS A REPORT LATE ON
FROM AUTHORITIES THAT SAID THE
GLASS HAD BEEN BROKEN, WHETHER
HE KICKED IT OUT, OR SHOT IT
OUT.
WHATEVER HAPPENED.
AND HE WENT IN THE SCHOOL, THIS
IS IMPORTANT TO NOTE.
THE FIRST REPORT WE HAVE OF
ACTUAL GUNFIRE OCCURRING IN THE
SCHOOL IS WHAT WAS REPORTED AT
9:36 IN THE MORNING, THAT IS
WHEN YOU HEAR THE FIRST POLICE
REPORT SAYING WE HAVE GUNFIRE
OCCURRING IN THE SCHOOL.
WE KNOW FROM WHAT WITNESSES SAID
THAT EVERYBODY WITHIN THE SCHOOL
KNEW THE GUNFIRE HAD STARTED, IN
PART BECAUSE SOME COULD ACTUALLY
HEAR THE GUNFIRE.
OTHERS HEARD IT OVER A P.A.
SYSTEM IN THE OFFICE, AND THEN
OTHERS CALLED AND SAID IS THAT
GUNFIRE?
THE AUTHORITIES SAY ALL THE
SHOOTING OCCURRED IN A VERY
SMALL AREA UP HERE NEAR THE
FRONT.
TWO ROOMS.
IT DID NOT SPREAD THROUGH THE
ENTIRE SCHOOL, EVEN THOUGH THERE
WERE 600 STUDENTS IN THE SCHOOL.
ANOTHER IMPORTANT TIME TO
CONSIDER HERE, 9:38.
I MENTIONED 9:38, BECAUSE BY
THAT TIME, IN A TWO AND A HALF
MINUTE SPAN, THIS IS THE TIME
WHERE THE AUTHORITIES SAY
THEY'RE HEARING THAT ALL THE
SHOOTING IS OVER.
AN INCREDIBLY SHORT PERIOD OF
TIME.
NOW I WILL SAY THERE WAS A
REPORT OF SHOTS, IT IS NOT CLEAR
IF SOMEBODY TOLD THEM THERE WERE
SHOTS OR IF THERE WAS SIMPLY A
DELAYED REPORT OF THE SHOTS.
BUT THE BULK OF THE SHOTS SEEMED
TO HAVE OCCURRED IN THIS VERY
SHORT WINDOW OF TIME.
THEN YOU MOVE TO 9:40 IN THE
MORNING, WHERE YOU GET THE CALL,
AT 9:43, FOR THE FIRST EMERGENCY
MEDICAL SERVICES.
TWO AMBULANCES WERE CALLED
INITIALLY ON POLICE RADIO.
AND A SHORT WHILE LATER, JUST A
MINUTE OR TWO LATER, THEY SAID
NO, WE HAVE MORE VICTIMS.
THEN THERE WAS SORT OF AN
INDEFINITE CALL FOR AS MANY
AMBULANCES AND EMS PEOPLE AS
THEY COULD GET TO THE SCHOOL.
BECAUSE THEY KNEW THEY HAD A
HUGE, HUGE PROBLEM ON THEIR
HANDS, AND THIS IS THE AMAZING
PART OF IT, WE PIECED TOGETHER
YESTERDAY.
WE HAVE MORE DETAILS, 9:40, WE
JUST PUT PLUS, PLUS, PLUS HERE,
BECAUSE IT HAS BEEN A LITTLE
LOOSE WITHIN THE TIME.
BUT WE CAN SAY BY SOME CERTAINTY
THAT BY 9:53, THE REPORTS WERE
THAT THIS WAS BASICALLY OVER
WITH.
THERE WAS AN AWFUL LOT MORE TO
DO.
BUT THE SIMPLE TRUTH, BY 9:53,
THE REPORT WAS THEY SAID THEY
HAD A SUSPECT DOWN.
OFFICERS SAID THEY HAD CLEARED
THE BUILDING.
IT IS NOT ENTIRELY CLEAR TO US
AT THIS POINT, MEANING THEY
CLEARED THE BUILDING OF POSSIBLE
SHOOTERS OR THEY HAD CLEARED THE
BUILDING OF POSSIBLE STUDENTS.
THIS PICTURE, BY THE WAY, FROM
THE NEWTOWN BEE.
IT IS NOT CLEAR IF THEY CLEARED
EVERYBODY OUT OR JUST THE
SUSPECT -- THEY WERE SEARCHING
THE ROOF OF THE BUILDING, AS
WELL.
BUT JUST AS WE REPORTED
YESTERDAY, WOLF, THE SIMPLE
TRUTH IS ALL THIS HAPPENED IN
ABOUT A 27-MINUTE TIME SPAN.
ALL OF IT HAPPENING IN A VERY
CLOSE AREA HERE.
WITH MUCH MORE INFORMATION AND
MUCH MORE DETAIL THAT IS WHERE
THEY'RE HOPING TO FIGURE OUT
SOME KIND OF WHY.
WHAT WAS THE THING THAT MADE
THIS PERSON COME TO THIS SCHOOL
AND DO THIS HORRIBLE, HORRIBLE
ATTACK.
WOLF?
>> THE INVESTIGATION OBVIOUSLY
CONTINUES.
SO MANY QUESTIONS HAVE TO BE
ANSWERED, TOM, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
LET'S BRING IN BRIAN TODD RIGHT
NOW.
HE HAS GOT A CLOSER LOOK AT THE
SHOOTER.
THE TWENTY-YEAR-OLD, ADAM LANZA,
YOU'RE GETTING NEW INFORMATION,
BRIAN, WHAT ARE YOU LEARNING?
>> Reporter: WELL, POLICE SAY
THEY HAVE PICKED UP EVIDENCE
ABOUT LANZA, AND HIS MOTHER,
PICKING UP EVIDENCE AT THE
HOUSE.
THEY'RE NOT LETTING ON WHAT THE
EVIDENCE IS.
BUT WE'RE GETTING NEW DETAILS
ABOUT THE SHOOTER'S PAST AND HIS
FAMILY.
HIS MOTIVE FOR THIS UNSPEAKABLE
ACT IS STILL NOT CLEAR, LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS SAY.
AND IN DIGGING FOR DETAILS ABOUT
SHOOTER ADAM LANZA AND HIS
FAMILY, THERE ARE CONFLICTING
REPORTS.
A NEIGHBOR WHO KNEW HIM IN
RECENT YEARS DESCRIBED HIM AS
TROUBLED.
BUT LISTEN TO THOSE WHO KNEW
HIM.
>> JUST A KID.
>> Reporter: NEVER ANTI-SOCIAL?
>> NO, NO.
>> Reporter: TROUBLE MAKER?
>> NO, DEFINITELY NOT.
>> Reporter: NOTICEABLE?
DID HE JUST KIND OF BLEND INTO
THE BACKGROUND?
>> YES, NOTHING THAT WOULD
WARRANT ANY OF THIS.
>> Reporter: RYAN CRAFT SAYS HE
BABYSAT LANZA ABOUT TEN YEARS
AGO WHEN HE WAS FIFTEEN, AND
LANZA WAS 10.
HE NEVER SAW ANYTHING THAT
WARRANTED VIOLENCE, BUT HE WOULD
OCCASIONALLY HAVE A TEMPER
TANTRUM.
>> HE WOULD BE WATCHING TV,
NORMAL STUFF THAT KIDS DO, BUT
AT TEN YEARS OLD, MOST KIDS GET
OUT OF THAT PHASE.
THAT WAS NOT THE CASE FOR ADAM.
>> Reporter: CRAFT WAS ONLY A
YEAR OVER ADAM'S OLDER BROTHER,
RYAN.
WHO SAID TO LET HIM DO WHAT HE
WANTED.
>> NANCY ALWAYS ASKED ME TO
ALWAYS BE WITH HIM IN THE ROOM,
NO MATTER WHAT.
LIKE DON'T GO TO THE BATHROOM.
DON'T EVER LEAVE HIM WITHOUT
SUPERVISION.
>> Reporter: CRAFT SAYS ADAM HAD
A CONTENTIOUS RELATIONSHIP WITH
HIS MOTHER, NANCY.
SHE HAD SPLIT WITH THE BOY'S
FATHER, PETER, WHO WAS DESCRIBED
AS TAX DIRECTOR AND VP AT GE
FINANCIAL SERVICES.
BUT CRAFT SAID THAT NANCY WAS AN
ENGAGED MOTHER, ALWAYS SETTING
UP PLAY DATES FOR HER TWO SONS
AND TAKING UP FAMILY ACTIVITIES.
NEIGHBORS SAY SHE ENJOYED
GARDENING AND HAD TAKEN TIME OUT
OF FINANCE.
>> JUST LIKE EVERYBODY, NORMAL,
YOU KNOW, DECORATE THE HOUSE,
THE HOUSE WAS ALWAYS PRISTINE.
AND THE HOUSE WAS LIKE ANY OTHER
HOUSE WIFE.
>> Reporter: BUT LIKE HER SON,
THERE ARE GAPS IN NANCY LANZA'S
STORY THAT STILL NEED TO BE
FILLED IN.
SHE OWNED THE WEAPONS THAT LANZA
USED, INCLUDING THE
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE, ACCORDING
TO A SOURCE.
AND IT IS NOT CLEAR WHY SHE
PURCHASED THOSE WEAPONS.
WOLF?
>> Reporter: BRIAN, ADAM LANZA
HAD ACCESS TO MORE WEAPONS THAN
THE ONES HE BROUGHT WITH HIM TO
THE SCHOOL.
>> >> THAT IS RIGHT, HE LIVED
WITH HIS MOTHER, AND LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS SAY HE HAD
MORE ACCESS TO WEAPONS THAN HE
TOOK TO THE SCHOOL.
AND PICKING UP ON THAT, THE
WEAPONS AT THE HOUSE I'M SURE
WE'LL LEARN ABOUT THAT IN THE
COMING DAYS.
>> WE JUST GOT A NEW PHOTO OF
ADAM LANZA.
I'LL SHOW IT TO THE VIEWERS,
THERE HE IS, AS A YOUNG BOY, HE
WAS ONLY TWENTY YEARS OLD WHEN
HE WENT TO THIS ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, KILLED 26 PEOPLE,
AND THEN KILLED HIMSELF.
EARLIER HE KILLED HIS MOTHER AT
THE FAMILY HOME HERE IN NEWTOWN.
THAT PICTURE JUST COMING IN.
BRIAN, WE'RE GOING TO BE GETTING
A LOT MORE INFORMATION ON THIS
TWENTY-YEAR-OLD.
AND GET MORE INFORMATION ON HIS
TWENTY-FOUR-YEAR-OLD BROTHER, AS
WELL WHO LIVES IN HOBOKEN, NEW
JERSEY.
>> WE WILL, AND HOPEFULLY WE'LL
BE PICKING UP A LOT MORE
INFORMATION.
OUR TEAMS ARE ON THE GROUND
THERE, AND WE'RE SCOPING OUT
INFORMATION WITH LAW
ENFORCEMENT.
AND HOPEFULLY WE'LL PIECE A LOT
OF THE STORY TOGETHER IN THE
NEXT COUPLE OF DAYS.
>> Reporter: YEAH, WE CERTAINLY
WI
WILL, BRIAN, LET'S GO BACK TO
KATE.
SHE IS WORKING THIS STORY, AS
WELL.
KATE, THE QUESTIONS CONTINUE.
>> Reporter: ABSOLUTELY, WOLF,
EACH ONE OF THE VICTIMS' STORIES
IS HEART-WRENCHING, AND IT
ABSOLUTELY BREAKS THEIR HEARTS.
WE SPOKE WITH THE COUSIN OF THE
FIRST GRADE TEACHER, VICKY SOTO,
WHO DIED TRYING TO PROTECT HER
CLASS, WHAT ARE YOU LEARNING,
JASON?
>> Reporter: WELL, IT IS JUST AN
INCREDIBLE STORY.
AND THERE ARE A LOT OF
INCREDIBLE STORIES, AS YOU KNOW,
KATE, WHEN YOU GO OVER AND TALK
TO SOME OF THE MEMBERS WHO KNEW
THE CHILDREN, AND FACULTY, AND
THE REASON WHY I'M STANDING IN
FRONT OF STRATFORD HIGH SCHOOL
IS THIS IS WHERE VICTORIA, VICKY
SOTO GRADUATED IN 2003.
SHE WAS DESCRIBED AS SOMEBODY
WHO JUST CARED ABOUT TEACHING,
REALLY WANTED TO BE A TEACHER
SINCE SHE WAS A LITTLE GIRL.
THAT IS THE PICTURE YOU SEE WITH
HER FAMILY.
THEY DESCRIBED HER AS SOMEBODY
WHO LOVED HER STUDENTS.
IN FACT, THEY TELL ME SHE NEVER
EVEN REFERRED TO HER STUDENTS AS
STUDENTS.
SHE CALLED THEM HER KIDS.
THEY TALKED A LITTLE BIT MORE
ABOUT WHY THEY'RE GOING TO BE
HOLDING A VIGIL HERE TONIGHT.
AND A LITTLE BIT MORE ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED IN THE CLASSROOM.
>> THE FAMILY DIDN'T WANT VICKY
JUST TO BE ANOTHER VICTIM ON A
PIECE OF PAPER.
VICKY WAS AN OUTSTANDING
TEACHER.
WELL LIKED, WELL RESPECTED IN
HER SCHOOL COMMUNITY.
AND SHE WAS TAKEN TOO EARLY.
SHE INSTINCTIVELY WENT INTO
ACTION WHEN A MONSTER CAME INTO
HER CLASS AND TRIED TO PROTECT
THE KIDS SHE LOVED SO MUCH.
>> Reporter: AND CAN YOU TELL ME
A LITTLE BIT MORE ABOUT HOW SHE
TRIED TO DO THAT?
>> WHAT WE WERE TOLD, SHE
GATHERED HER CHILDREN INTO A
CLOSET AND PUT HERSELF IN HARM'S
WAY, IN BETWEEN THE GUNMAN AND
THE KIDS.
AND WE JUST WANT THE PUBLIC TO
KNOW THAT VICKY WAS A HERO.
REGARDLESS OF THE INTIMATE
DETAILS THAT TOOK PLACE IN THAT
CLASSROOM, VICKY WAS DOING WHAT
SHE KNEW WAS RIGHT IN HER HEART,
AND WHAT SHE WAS TRAINED TO DO,
TO PROTECT HER KIDS.
>> Reporter: AND SOME OF THOSE
WHO ARE GOING TO THE VIGIL HAVE
ALREADY STARTED TO GATHER HERE
TONIGHT.
EXPECTED TO ATTEND, KATE, ARE
THEY ARE TWO SISTERS WHO YOU SEE
IN THE PICTURE.
HER MOTHER IS EXPECTED TO BE
HERE TONIGHT.
HER FATHER, AS WELL.
HER COUSIN WHO YOU JUST HEARD
FROM THERE.
I'M TOLD THAT WHAT HER FAMILY
SAYS THEY'RE TRYING TO DO IS
TELLING PEOPLE IN THE COMMUNITY
WHO ARE COMING OUT.
TRY TO FIND GREEN HATS, AND
GLOVES, ANYTHING THAT IS GREEN.
BECAUSE GREEN IS ONE OF HER
FAVORITE COLORS.
APPARENTLY THERE IS GOING TO BE
SINGING OUT HERE, THE CHOIR WILL
BE HERE.
IT IS VERY HARD TO COPE.
ONE STORY IN PARTICULAR RESON  E
RESONATED WITH ME, THEY TALKED
ABOUT ONE THING VICKY CARED
ABOUT DEEPLY.
HER BLACK LAB, ROXY, WHO IS
WALKING AROUND THE APARTMENT,
WAITING FOR HER TO COME HOME.
AND OF COURSE, THAT IS HOW HER
FAMILY IS FEELING, WAITING FOR
HER TO COME HOME.
ANOTHER REASON THEY'RE HOLDING
THIS VIGIL, IS BECAUSE THEY WANT
THE WORLD NOT TO SEE HER AS JUST
ANOTHER VICTIM.
THEY WANT THE WORLD TO SEE HER
AS A DEDICATED TEACHER, A LOVING
SISTER, AND A LOVING DAUGHTER,
KATE.
>> Reporter: JASON, I'M SURE
THAT VICKY SOTO'S FAMILY ALREADY
KNOWS THIS.
BUT I SAT DOWN WITH THE PARENT
OF ONE OF HER FIRST GRADE
STUDENTS, AND THEY COULD NOT SAY
ENOUGH WONDERFUL THINGS ABOUT
HER AS A TEACHER, SAYING THAT
THEIR SON, WHO SHE PROTECTED,
WHO HE WAS ABLE TO GET OUT ALIVE
AND RUN TO SAFETY, SAID HE CARED
ABOUT HIS TEACHER VERY, VERY
MUCH.
SO I AM SURE THEY WOULD WANT TO
PASS ALONG THAT STATEMENT TO
VICKY SOTO'S FAMILY, THANK YOU,
VERY MUCH, JASON.
COPING WITH UNSPEAKABLE TRAGEDY,
NOT ONLY FOR THE FAMILIES OF THE
DEAD BUT ALSO THE VICTIMS.
>> THE PRINCIPAL, WHO GOD BLESS
HER, LOST HER LIFE, WAS JUST --
A VERY SPECIAL PERSON.
AND ALL THE PARENTS KNEW THAT.
THERE'S A HEALTH COMPANY THAT
CAN HELP YOU STAY THAT WAY.
WHAT'S HEALTHIER THAN THAT?
HOW THEY'LL LIVE TOMORROW.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
BUSHWACK
.
>>> WE'RE CONTINUING OUR SPECIAL
COVERAGE OF THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL KILLING HERE IN
CONNECTICUT.
SOLEDAD O'BRIEN IS HERE, AND SHE
HAD A HEART-WRENCHING INTERVIEW
WITH ONE OF THE PARENTS.
>> WHEN WE WENT DOWN TO THE FIRE
HOUSE TO GET OUR CHILDREN, WE
WERE UNAWARE OF THE REAL TRAGEDY
AT HAND.
I DID NOT THINK CHILDREN WERE
INVOLVED.
I THOUGHT THIS WAS ISOLATED, A
COUPLE OF TEACHERS, MAYBE EVEN
JUST ONE.
SO WHEN WE GOT OUR CHILDREN AND
I SAW MY SON'S TEACHER -- THEY
WERE LIKE GHOSTS.
BUT THEY'RE INCREDIBLY COMPOSED.
THEY HAD THEIR SHEETS WITH THEM,
CHECKING OFF, MAKING SURE EACH
CHILD WENT WITH THEIR PARENT.
THEY -- THEY DID EVERYTHING
POSSIBLE TO KEEP OUR CHILDREN
SAFE.
EVERYTHING, AND I WISH I HAD
KNOWN WHEN I LOOKED AT THEIR
FACES JUST TO SAY THANK YOU,
BECAUSE I HAVE MY CHILDREN.
>> Reporter: OUR CHIEF MEDICAL
CORRESPONDENT, DR. SANJAY GUPTA
IS STILL WITH ME.
WE'RE GOING TO TALK RIGHT NOW TO
AN EXPERT IN CHILDHOOD TRAUMA,
SHE IS THE DIRECTOR OF TERROR
AND DISASTER PROGRAMS AT UCLA
DUKE CENTER FOR CHILDREN.
DR. BRENT, THANK YOU VERY MUCH
FOR JOINING US.
WHAT IS THE MOST IMPORTANT
ADVICE YOU GIVE PARENTS WHOSE
CHILDREN MAY HAVE EXPERIENCED
TRAUMA, HORRIFIC EVENT LIKE
THIS?
>> THE PARENTS ARE GOING THROUGH
JUST TREMENDOUS AMOUNTS OF
STRESS.
AND IT IS IMPORTANT FOR ALL OF
US TO GIVE THEM AS MUCH SUPPORT.
THEY HAVE A LOT OF DEMANDS ON
THEM RIGHT NOW IN TERMS OF HOW
TO TALK TO THEIR KIDS RIGHT NOW.
HOW TO PROVIDE THOSE COMFORTS.
AND THERE IS GREAT PEOPLE IN
CONNECTICUT AND ALL AROUND THAT
KNOW WHAT THEY'RE DOING THAT CAN
LEND SUPPORT TO THEM AT THIS
TIME.
AND DOCTOR, IT IS SANJAY GUPTA,
ONE OF THE THINGS THAT COME UP
HERE QUITE A BIT, IS THE
CHILDREN WHO ARE IN THE SCHOOL,
YOU KNOW, HOW LONG WILL THE
SYMPTOMS AND THE CONCERNS ABOUT
PTSD LAST FOR THEM?
>> WE HAVE LEARNED FROM OTHER
TYPES OF EVENTS.
I HAVE WORKED AT SANTANA HIGH
SCHOOL AND OTHER SCHOOL
SHOOTINGS, AND ALSO AFTER
NORWAY.
WE KNOW THAT FOR SOME PORTION OF
THE KIDS IT IS GOING TO BE A
LONG-TERM EVENT.
AND WE NEED FOR MAKE SURE THAT
WE HAVE RESOURCES AND PROGRAMS
IN PLACE IN THE SCHOOL AND IN
THE COMMUNITY FOR THE NEXT
SEVERAL MONTHS AND SEVERAL YEARS
TO SUPPORT THOSE WHO NEED IT.
NOT EVERYBODY WILL NEED THAT
LEVEL OF SUPPORT.
>> GO AHEAD.
>> IS IT POSSIBLE TO PREDICT,
DOCTOR, ARE CHILDREN -- ARE THEY
MORE RESILIENT THAN ADULTS?
ARE THEY LESS RESILIENT?
HOW WOULD YOU CHARACTERIZE IT?
>> THERE ARE A LOT OF KIDS WHO
ARE GOING TO ABSOLUTELY BE
RESILIENT.
BUT WE ALSO HAVE TO THINK NOT
JUST FROM THE PTSD SIDE OF
THINGS, THESE FAMILIES ARE
MOURNING.
AND THEY'RE DEALING WITH GRIEF.
AND WE HAVE TO MAKE SURE THAT
THE SERVICES WE PROVIDE ADDRESS
THOSE GRIEF ISSUES.
AND THAT SOMETIMES BECAUSE OF
THEIR EXPERIENCES THEY MAY NOT
BE ABLE TO BE GRIEVING OR
MOURNING RIGHT NOW.
THAT BECAUSE OF WHAT THEY SAW
AND THEY EXPERIENCED, THE TRAUMA
PIECE OF IT IS GETTING IN THE
WAY.
SO WE NEED TO MAKE SURE OUR
SERVICES ARE PROVIDING BOTH THE
TRAUMA AND THE GRIEF SUPPORT.
>> I KNOW THE CONVENTIONAL, THE
INSTINCTIVE IMAGE, THE INSTINCT
IS, DR. BRIMER, IS FOR PARENTS
NOT TO BREAK DOWN, START SHOWING
REALLY DEEP EMOTIONS IN FRONT OF
THE KIDS, BECAUSE THE KIDS WILL
START TO GET SCARED.
IS THAT SMART, THOUGH?
SHOULD THE PARENTS TRY TO AVOID
THAT?
>> THERE IS NO WAY THAT PARENTS
ARE GOING TO AVOID WHAT THEIR
FEELINGS ARE.
AND THEY ARE GOING TO EXPRESS
JUST HOW AWFUL AND HOW TRAGIC
THIS HAS BEEN.
BUT IT IS ALSO IMPORTANT THAT
PARENTS GET SUPPORT FROM OTHER
ADULTS IN THEIR LIVES.
WHETHER IT IS CLERGY OR OTHER
LOVED ONES THAT CAN SUPPORT THEM
IN A MUCH MORE WAY THAT THEY
CAN'T GET FROM THEIR CHILDREN.
>> WHAT ABOUT AGE?
AND MAYBE THERE IS NOT A GREAT
ANSWER TO THIS, DOCTOR.
BUT THESE CHILDREN ARE SO YOUNG.
I MEAN, IS THERE A WAY TO -- IS
THERE A SPECIFIC THING THAT YOU
SHOULD AVOID WHEN TALKING TO
THEM, OR SPECIFIC THINGS THAT
THEY SHOULD ABSOLUTELY BE
HEARING NOW IN THESE COUPLE OF
DAYS?
>> I THINK IT IS VERY IMPORTANT
THAT WE'RE HONEST WITH THEM.
AS YOU TALKED ABOUT EARLIER, WE
HAVE TO TALK BASED ON THEIR AGE
LEVEL AND SO WE HAVE TO BE VERY,
VERY CONCRETE AND KEEP OUR
ANSWERS SHORT.
AND THEY'RE GOING TO HAVE TO
SOMETIMES -- WE HAVE TO REVISIT
THESE CONVERSATIONS.
BUT IT IS IMPORTANT TO ANSWER
THEIR QUESTIONS HONESTLY.
AND PROVIDE THEM COMFORT.
WE KNOW THAT A LOT OF IT IS
TERMS OF SAFETY, AND HOW DO WE
HELP THEM.
THINK ABOUT THOSE CONCERNS OF
SAFETY.
AND YOUNGER KIDS BRING IT TO
HOME.
SO THEY'RE GOING TO ASK
QUESTIONS, AM I SAFE AT HOME
RIGHT NOW?
ARE YOU SAFE?
AND WE CAN PROVIDE THOSE TYPES
OF REASSURANCES TO THEM.
>> AND VERY QUICKLY, SHOULD THE
KIDS GET BACK TO THEIR ROUTINES
IN DEALING WITH THIS?
IN OTHER WORDS, SHOULD THEY GO
BACK TO SCHOOL ON MONDAY?
>> I THINK IT IS IMPORTANT TO
GET THOSE KIDS BACK TO SCHOOL.
THEY MAY NOT BE DOING THOSE TYPE
OF THINGS AT SCHOOL.
THEY MAY NOT BE READY TO LEARN.
BUT SCHOOL CAN BE THAT EXTRA
LEVEL OF SUPPORT FOR FAMILIES
RIGHT NOW.
WE CAN HAVE EXTRA PROFESSIONALS
THERE AT SCHOOLS, TEACHERS CAN
MONITOR.
OTHER PEOPLE CAN MONITOR HOW
THESE KIDS ARE DOING, CAN ANSWER
QUESTIONS AND PROVIDE A SUPPORT.
SO WE HAVE FOUND THAT RETURNING
BACK TO A ROUTINE CAN BE VERY
HELPFUL TO THEIR RECOVERY.
>> DR. MELISSA BRIMER, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH FOR THAT EXPERTISE.
WE REALLY APPRECIATE IT.
>> THANK YOU.
AND I HOPE YOU GUYS ARE TAKING
CARE OF YOURSELF DURING THIS
TIME.
>> WELL, IT IS NOT EASY, I GOT
TO TELL YOU, SANJAY, THIS IS A
TOUGH ASSIGNMENT.
YOU AND I HAVE COVERED WARS AND
ASSIGNMENTS.
I THINK THIS IS ONE OF THE MOST
DIFFICULT.
>> I THINK THAT WATCHING THE
PARENTS, THAT WAS HARD, WOLF.
I TELL YOU, YOU AND I ARE BOTH
DADS.
AND I THINK THAT IS THE HARDEST
THING I HAVE SEEN.
AND I'LL JUST FOLLOW UP ON
SOMETHING YOU ASKED ME
PREVIOUSLY.
COLUMBINE WAS IN APRIL THAT
YEAR.
AND THE SCHOOL DID NOT OPEN
AGAIN UNTIL AUGUST AFTER THE
SUMMER BREAK.
SO IT IS GOING TO BE TOUGH TO
THINK HOW THEY WILL DECIDE THAT
HERE.
AND I DON'T KNOW IF THERE IS AN
EXACT ANSWER IN TERMS OF WHEN
THEY SHOULD GO BACK TO SCHOOL.
YOU HAVE ASKED.
AND WE'LL SEE.
>> AND WE THOUGHT THE STORY, THE
POISON GAS WAS A HARD STORY, IN
HINDSIGHT, THIS IS MUCH MORE
DIFFICULT.
>> I GUESS BECAUSE OF THESE
PARENTS AND CHILDREN, EVERYBODY
WATCHING RIGHT NOW THINKS THAT
WHAT IF THAT WERE MY CHILD?
AND I KEEP SEEING IT IN MY OWN
CHILDREN'S FACES, I AM SURE YOU
ARE TOO.
>> FOR THE FIRST FEW MOMENTS
AFTER THE SHOOTING, THE TERROR
WAS MULTIPLED, KATE TALKED ABOUT
THAT.
SO WHAT CAUSED HILLARY CLINTON
TO FAINT, FALL DOWN AND SUFFER A
CONCUSSION?
>> THANK YOU, THANK YOU FOR --
Quicken Loans?
AT Quicken Loans, WE'LL PROVIDE
YOU WITH MYQL MOBILE.
THIS AMAZINGLY USEFUL APP
ALLOWS YOU
TO TAKE PICTURES
OF YOUR MORTGAGE DOCUMENTS
USING AN iPhone
OR Android SMART PHONE...
SO YOU CAN EASILY
SEND THEM TO US.
ONE MORE WAY Quicken Loans
IS Engineered to Amaze.
OOH, LA-LA!
YOU WON'T TAKE OUR FUTURE.
AIDS AFFECTS US ALL.
EVEN BABIES.
CHEVRON IS WORKING TO STOP
MOTHER-TO-CHILD TRANSMISSION.
OUR EMPLOYEES AND THEIR FAMILIES
ARE PART OF THE FIGHT.
AND WE'RE WINNING.
AT CHEVRON NIGERIA, WE HAVEN'T
HAD A REPORTED CASE IN 12 YEARS.
AIDS IS STRONG.
BUT WE ARE STRONGER.
AND AIDS...
♪
AIDS IS GOING TO LOSE.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
TRAUMATIZ
.
>>> JUST A LITTLE WHILE AGO I
TALKED TO TWO SPIRITUAL LEADERS,
WHO ARE HELPING THOSE HERE COPE
WITH THE LOSS.
WE'RE HERE AT A DATH, ISRAEL,
AND BOTH OF YOU, REVEREND, HAVE
BEEN SPENDING A LOT OF TIME WITH
FAMILY MEMBERS, HOW IS THAT
GOING?
>> IT IS REALLY TOUGH IN
NEWTOWN.
AND IT IS THE WORST TRAGEDY THAT
I HAVE SEEN IN MY LIFE.
AND IT IS VERY HARD TO CONSOLE A
PARENT WHO JUST DISCOVERED THEIR
CHILDREN WERE AMONG THE VICTIMS.
>> AND REVEREND, YOU HAVE MET
WITH PARENTS WHO HAVE LOST KIDS?
>> YES, WE WERE BOTH THERE IN
THE FIRE HOUSE WITH THE FAMILIES
DURING THAT WHOLE PROCESS.
AND IT WAS JUST INDESCRIBABLE IN
TERMS OF THE GRIEF AND THE
WAITING AND TRYING TO BE PRESENT
TO THEM, AND ALSO TO MANY OF THE
FOLKS THAT WERE WORKING WITH
EMERGENCY SERVICES, AND POLICE,
AND OTHERS WHO THEMSELVES WERE
JUST SORROW OF THE
MAGNITUDE THAT WAS HAPPENING.
>> RABBI, IS THERE ONE MOMENT
YESTERDAY WHEN YOU WERE THE
FIREHOUSE WITH THESE FAMILIES
THAT STANDS OUT THAT YOU'LL
NEVER FORGET IN YOUR LIFE?
>> YEAH, THERE'S SOME VERY
UNSHAKABLE IMAGES AND THAT'S
WHEN THE NEWS CAME FROM THE
GOVERNOR, THAT THE CHILDREN DID
NOT MAKE IT AND THE WAILING OF
THE PARENTS AND SORT OF THE
GROPING AND TRYING TO REACH FOR
SOMETHING INTANGIBLE.
IT WAS HORRIFIC, TERRIBLE SCENE.
>> YOU WERE THERE, TOO?
>> I WAS THERE, TOO IT WAS FROM
MY PERSPECTIVE, HOLY GROUND.
AND AS PEOPLE HAVE TALKED TO ME
AND ASKED ME ABOUT IT, I TIP
CALI TELL PEOPLE, IT WAS HOLY
GROUND AND HONOR THE HOLINESS OF
THAT PLACE AND SPACE AND THE
PEOPLE THAT WERE THERE AS BEST
I'M ABLE.
IT'S SOMETHING YOU NEVER WANT TO
HAVE TO BE IN A ROOM LIKE THAT
EVER AGAIN.
BUT IN THE TRAGEDY, THERE IS A
SENSE OF THE HOLINESS OF IT,
UNMITIGATED LOSS AND TRAGEDY AND
HONORING THAT AND HONORING THOSE
FAMILIES IN THEIR GRIEF.
>> WE NEED TO HAVE A CULTURE OF
PEACE AND THAT SO MANY OF THE
YOUNG GAMES THAT WE HAVE AS
CHILDREN, VERY YOUNG AGES IS
ABOUT WAR AND KILLING AND THAT
WE CAN MAKE -- WE'RE AN
INTELLIGENT COUNTRY, WE CAN MAKE
WONDERFUL GAMES THAT HAVE TO DO
WITH PEACE MAKING AND DIPLOMACY
AND IT DOESN'T TAKE ANY
INTELLIGENCE TO PULL A TRIGGER
AND BLOW SOMEBODY'S BRAINS OUT.
>> WHAT ARE YOU SUGGESTING?
THE SHOOTER IN THIS PARTICULAR
CASE GREW UP IN A CULTURE OF
VIOLENCE?
>> YES, THAT OUR ENTIRE
CIVILIZATION IS TOO INUNDATED
WITH CULTURE OF VIOLENCE, THERE
CAN BE AN INCENTIVE AND A FUN
GAME THAT HAS TO DO WITH
LEARNING ABOUT OTHER PEOPLE IN
THE WORLD AND DEALING WITH
GRIEVANCES THROUGH ACTIVE
DIPLOMACY.
>> SO MANY PEOPLE HAVE SAID TO
ME, REVEREND, AND RABBI, HOW CAN
GOD ALLOW SOMETHING LIKE THIS TO
HAPPEN.
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
>> ONE OF THE THINGS I FIRST SAY
IN THIS MOMENT IS THIS IS NOT
THE MOMENT TO ANSWER THAT
QUESTION, AT LEAST NOT TO THE
FAMILIES THAT ARE IN GRIEF.
I THINK THERE ARE ANSWERS, THERE
ARE ANSWER FROM MY TRADITION
THAT SPEAK TO SUFFERING AND HOW
SUFFERING CAN BE TRANSFORMATIVE,
HOW AS A CHRISTIAN I UNDERSTAND
THAT THERE ARE WAYS IN WHICH WE
CAN TRANSFORM AND BE TRANSFORMED
IN THE MIDST OF SUFFERING.
TO BE HONEST WITH YOU, THAT'S
NOT A QUESTION THAT I TRY TO
ANSWERER TODAY BECAUSE PEOPLE
DON'T NEED TO HEAR WHAT BECOMES
AN OVERSIMPLISTIC ANSWER TO
SOMETHING SO DEEP AND PROFOUND.
>> WHAT WILL BE THE CENTRAL
MESSAGE THAT YOU TELL YOUR
CONGREGATION TOMORROW MORNING
IN.
>> I WILL BE PREACHING A MESSAGE
THAT EVEN IN THE MIDST OF
DARKNESS THERE IS LIGHT.
IT'S TRAJ THANK WE ARE IN THE
MIDST OF A SEASON FOR US AS
CHRISTIANS, WAS CHRISTMASTIME
AND ADVENT AND IT'S A HOLY TIME
FOR US.
BUT WE ALSO KNOW THAT IN THE
MIDST OF A SEASON THAT SO OFTEN
WE ASSOCIATE WITH JOY AND
MERRIMENT, THAT IT'S ALSO A
SEASON OF DARKNESS AND, IN FACT,
THE GOSPEL OF JOHN TELLS US
LIGHT SHINES IN THE DARKNESS AND
THE DARKNESS DOES NOT OVERCOME
IT.
I'LL BE PREACHING A MESSAGE THAT
PROMISES IN THE MIDST OF THE
DARK TIMES THAT WE KNOW THE
LIGHT OF GOD IS WITH US AND THAT
WE CAN BE SUSTAINED IN THAT AND
WE CAN SEE THAT LIGHT IN EACH
OTHER AND DRAW FROM THAT LIGHT
THAT IS A PART OF OUR FAITH.
>> THE MOST IMPORTANT THING THAT
WE CAN DO AS I REACTION TO THIS
IS THRIVE.
I SET MY BANQUET IN THE PRESENCE
OF THE ENEMIES.
THE ENEMY IS THE HORRIBLE EVENT
AND THE BANQUET IS CONTINUING
OUR THRIVING IN LIFE.
I LIVED IN ISRAEL FOR TEN YEARS
AND SAW THE WAY THE ISRAELIS
WOULD PICK UP AND GO TO THE SPOT
WHERE SOMETHING TERRIBLE
HAPPENED AND THE MESSAGE WAS WE
CARRY ON.
WE WILL CARRY ON.
WE HAVE GREAT SCHOOLS IN
NEWTOWN.
THIS WAS AN ISOLATED INCIDENT.
THIS EVENT DOESN'T DEFINE US.
WE WILL CONTINUE TO HAVE GREAT
SCHOOLS.
AND BE THE GATE COMMUNITY.
MATTHEW AND I ARE GREAT FRIENDS
AND ALL OF THE CLERGY ARE GREAT
FRIENDS, AND WE WILL RECOVER.
>> RABBI, REVEREND, THANKS SO
MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
>> WE'RE GOING TO HAVE MUCH MORE
ON THE MASS KILLING HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, YESTERDAY.
BUT THERE'S ANOTHER MAJOR STORY
DEVELOPING TODAY.
I WANT TO UPDATE OUR VIEWERS IN
THE WAS AROUND THE WORLD.
NEWS THAT THE SECRETARY OF
STATE, HILLARY CLINTON,
SUSTAINED A CONCUSSION AFTER
FAINTING.
OUR FOREIGN AFFAIRS REPORTER
ELISE LAVIN IS JOINING US WITH
THE LATEST INFORMATION WE'RE
GETTING.
WHAT DO WE HE KNOW?
>> Reporter: OVER THE WEEK,
SECRETARY OF STATE CLINTON GOT A
STOMACH VIRUS, AS YOU KNOW THAT
PUT HER OUT FOR THE WHOLE WEEK.
SHE CAUGHT THAT ON A TRIP TO
EUROPE.
SHE HAD TO CANCEL HER TRIP TO
THE MIDDLE EAST WHERE SHE WAS
EXPECTED TO ATTEND A BIG MEETING
ON SYRIA.
NOW WE HEAR THE SECOND SUFFERED
A LOT OF DEHYDRATION, FAINTED
AND WE'RE TOLD, HER DOCTORS SAY,
OVER THE COURSE OF THE WEEK THEY
REALIZED WHEN SHE FAINTED SHE
SUFFERED A CONCUSSION.
LET ME READ YOU A STATEMENT FROM
HER SPOKESMAN, DEPUTY ASSISTANT
SECRETARY.
WHILE SUFFERING FROM A STOMACH
VIRUS SECRETARY CLINTON BECAME
DEHYDRATED AND FAINTED
SUSTAINING A CONCUSSION.
SHE'S BEEN RECOVERING AT HOME
AND WILL CONTINUE TO BE
MONITORED REGULARLY BY HER
DOCTORS.
AT THEIR RECOMMENDATION, SHE
WILL CONTINUE TO WORK FROM HOME
NEXT WEEK, STAYING IN CONTACT
WITH DEPARTMENT AND OTHER
OFFICIALS.
WOLF, I'M TOLD THIS CONCUSSION
WAS NOT SEVERE AND THAT
SECRETARY DOES INTEND TO COME
BACK TO WORK AFTER SOME
RECUPERATION AND HER DOCTOR SAID
IN A STATEMENT SHE WILL MAKE A
FULL RECOVERY.
>> I'M SURE SHE WILL MAKE A FULL
RECOVERY.
WE'RE HOPING FOR THAT, OF
COURSE.
ELISE, THANKS VERY MUCH.
LET'S BRING BACK CHIEF MEDICAL
CORRESPONDENT, SANJAY GUPTA.
THE STATEMENT FROM THE DOCTORS
IS INTERESTING.
IT GOES BEYOND WHAT THE OFFICIAL
STATE DEPARTMENT STATEMENT SAID.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
PEOPLE HAVE MAYBE SEEN THIS BUT
IT SAYS OVER THE COURSE OF THE
WEEK THEY EVALUATED HER AND
ULTIMATELY DETERMINED SHE
SUSTAINED A CONCUSSION.
WHAT THIS MEANS, OBVIOUSLY, THIS
DIDN'T HAPPEN TODAY.
THIS -- SHE HAD A FAINTING
EPISODE, HIT HER HEAD, THAT
HAPPENED EARLIER IN THE WEEK AND
DOCTORS EXAMINING HER AND
DETERMINING SHE HAD A CONCUSSION
AFTER THAT.
THEY'RE ALSO SAYING NO STRENUOUS
ACTIVITY.
OFTENTIMES THEY ADD TO THAT,
WHICH YOU MAY FIND INTERESTING,
YOU DON'T WANT TO -- YOU ALMOST
WANT TO GIVE THE BRAIN REST AS
WELL.
DOCTORS WILL LITERALLY SAY DON'T
READ ANYTHING, DON'T WATCH
TELEVISION, DON'T GET ON A
COMPUTER.
YOU WANT TO PUT THE BRAIN TO
REST FOR A WHILE TO ALLOW THE
BRAIN TO RECOVER FROM A
CONCUSSION.
>> BECAUSE THE AT THE SAME TIME
FROM THE STATE DEPARTMENT, HER
SPOKESMAN, BASICALLY SAID SHE'S
WORKING FROM HOME.
THE DOCTORS ARE SAYING THEY
STRONGLY ADVISE HER TO CANCEL
ALL WORK EVENTS FOR THE COMING
WEEK.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
THIS IS PROBABLY SOME OF THE
FRICTION SOMETIMES WEAN DOCTORS
AND WHAT PATIENTS WANT TO DO.
I IMAGINE IT'S GOING TO BE HARD
TO GET HER NOT TO DO ANYTHING AT
ALL.
THE BEST WAY TO GET FULL
RECOVERY FROM A CONCUSSION IS
NOT DO ANYTHING.
THIS IS MORE THAN ANECDOTAL.
THOSE IS SOMETHING WE KNOW --
I'VE DONE A LOT OF REPORTING, AS
YOU KNOW, ON CONCUSSIONS -- THIS
IS VERY IMPORTANT.
OBVIOUSLY SHE'S SECRETARY OF
STATE BUT THIS IS VERY IMPORTANT
FOR HER TO RECOVER AS WELL SHE'S
CAN.
>> SHE WAS SUPPOSED TO APPEAR
BEFORE THE HOUSE AND SENATE THIS
WEEK ON DECEMBER 20th ON THE
BENGHAZI KILLING OF THE FOUR
AMERICANS INCLUDING THE U.S.
AMBASSADOR, STATE DEPARTMENT
REPORT ABOUT TO RELEASED ON WHAT
EXACT HI HAPPENED.
SHE OBVIOUSLY CAN'T DO THAT.
THEY'VE ANNOUNCED SHE CAN'T
APPEAR P
APPEAR.
SHE'S SENDING TWO DEPUTIES.
>> THAT'S THE BRAIN REST.
RECOVERING FROM A CONCUSSION
WOULD NOT -- THAT WOULD NOT BE
ON THE AGENDA.
>> ASSUME IT'S A MILE
CONCUSSION.
SHE'S AT HOME, NOT IN THE
HOSPITAL.
THEY DETERMINED SHE HAD A
CONCUSSION.
BRAIN REST IS VERY IMPORTANT.
BUT HOW LONG?
HOW LONG SHOULD SOMEBODY AVOID
ANY MENTAL REAL STRENUOUS
ACTIVITY?
>> WHAT YOU WANT TO DO IS TRIAL
SOMEBODY.
SO YOU MIGHT -- MY GUESS IS WHAT
HAS HAPPENED SHE CONTINUED TO
HAVE SYMPTOMS AFTER THIS, MAYBE
HEADACHE, MAYBE BLURRINESS OF
VISION, IT DID NOT CLEAR AS
QUICKLY AS THEY WOULD HAVE
LIKED.
THEY DETERMINED IT WAS A
CONCUSSION.
YOU SLOWLY REINTRODUCE ACTIVITY,
ALLOW SOMEONE TO START READING,
ENGAGING IN EXERCISE, AND SEEING
IF ANY OF THE SYMPTOMS COME
BACK.
IF THEY COME BACK, YOU'RE BACK
ON REST AGAIN.
SO IT CAN BE BACK AND FORTH FOR
A LITTLE BIT.
MY GUESS IS A WEEK.
THAT'S TYPICALLY WITH A MILD
CONCUSSION, HOW THEY'RE
CHARACTERIZING IT, THAT'S THE
TYPICAL TIME FRAME.
AGAIN, BEING THEY LET HER BE
HOME, THROUGHOUT THE ENTIRE
TIME, I THINK THEY OBVIOUSLY
WOULD HAVE A LOW THRESHOLD FOR
HAVING HER IN THE HOSPITAL IN
THIS CASE, SHE'S NOT.
SO I THINK THE