THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
>> I'LL BE BACK TOMORROW NIGHT
FOR A SPECIAL EDITIONS OF "A.C.
360" FROM NEWTOWN AT 8:00 AND
10:00 TOMORROW.
BUT OUR COVERAGE CONTINUES RIGHT
NOW.
>>> HELLO, EVERYONE, FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, A SMALL
TOWN, VIRTUALLY UNKNOWN UNTIL
YESTERDAY WHEN IT BECAME THE
SCENE OF ONE OF THE WORST MASS
KILLINGS IN AMERICAN HISTORY.
I'M DON LEMON.
LET ME PASS ON SOME NEW
DEVELOPMENTS THAT HAVE COME JUST
THIS EVENING.
THE FATHER OF THE ALLEGED
SHOOTER, WE'VE HEARD FROM.
PETER LANZA RELEASED A
STATEMENT, PART OF IT SAYS,
QUOTE, OUR FAMILY IS GRIEVING
ALONG WITH ALL THOSE WHO HAVE
BEEN AFFECTED BY THIS ENORMOUS
TRAGEDY.
NO WORDS CAN TRULY EXPRESS HOW
HEARTBROKEN WE ARE.
HE IS THE FATHER OF ADAM LANZA.
THIS IS A PICTURE OF HIM FROM
JUST A FEW YEARS AGO.
HE IS NOW 20 YEARS OLD WHO
POLICE SAY WALKED INTO AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL YESTERDAY AND
JUST STARTED SHOOTING.
20 CHILDREN, ALL OF THEM 6 OR 7
YEARS OLD, WERE KILLED.
SIX ADULTS, TEACHERS AND STAFF,
INCLUDING THE PRINCIPAL, THEY'RE
ALL DEAD NOW, TOO.
THE SHOOTER KILLED HIMSELF.
THIS IS WHERE POLICE ARE TRYING
TO ANSWER ALL THE QUESTIONS.
THEY'RE TRYING TO ANSWER THE
QUESTIONS WHY.
THE LANZA HOME, NOT FAR FROM THE
SCHOOL.
IT'S ALSO WHERE THE SUSPECTED
SHOOTER'S MOTHER WAS FOUND DEAD
AS WELL.
TODAY, THE FATHER AND AUNT OF
ONE OF THE SHOOTING VICTIMS IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WENT
BEFORE CAMERAS TO REMEMBER A
CHILD THEY DESCRIBED AS
INCREDIBLE BUT IN REMEMBERING
LITTLE EMILIE PARKER, THEY SAID,
THEY'RE PRAYING FOR THE
SHOOTER'S FAMILY, TOO, BECAUSE
THAT'S WHAT SHE WOULD HAVE
WANTED.
KYUNG LAH WAS THERE.
KYUNG, WHAT STUCK OUT TO YOU
MOST OF ALL WHEN YOU WERE
TALKING TO THESE PEOPLE AND YOU
WATCHED ALL OF THIS?
>> THE ABILITY OF THEM TO BE
ABLE TO STILL THINK OF OTHER
PEOPLE AND SOCIETY IN THE FACE
OF AN UNSPEAKABLE LOSS.
IF YOU'RE A PARENT, IF YOU HAVE
CHILDREN WHO YOU LOVE AND YOU
THINK ABOUT THIS HAPPENING TO
YOURSELF, IT'S REALLY HARD TO
COMPREHEND, THEN BEING ABLE TO
FACE NATIONAL CAMERAS, REPORTERS
AND MAKE A STATEMENT ABOUT
SOCIETY.
BUT THAT'S WHAT THIS FAMILY HAS
DONE.
AND HERE IS A LITTLE BIT OF WHAT
THEY SAID.
>> EMILIE WAS A MENTOR TO HER
TWO LITTLE SISTERS AND DELIGHTED
IN TEACHING THEM HOW TO READ,
DANCE AND FIND THE SIMPLE JOYS
IN LIFE.
EMILIE'S LAUGHTER WAS INFECTIOUS
AND ALL THOSE WHO HAD THE
PLEASURE TO MEET HER WOULD AGREE
THAT THIS WORLD IS A BETTER
PLACE BECAUSE SHE'S BEEN IN IT.
>> EMILIE ALICE PARKER WAS THE
SWEETEST LITTLE GIRL I'VE EVER
KNOWN.
MY CHILDREN ARE GRIEVING.
MY SIBLINGS ACROSS THE COUNTRY
ARE GRIEVING AND WE'RE JUST
DEVASTATED THAT SOMEONE SO
BEAUTIFUL AND PERFECT IS NO
LONGER GOING TO BE IN OUR LIVES
AND FOR NO REASON.
>> AS WE MOVE ON FROM WHAT
HAPPENED HERE, WHAT HAPPENED TO
SO MANY PEOPLE, LET IT NOT TURN
INTO SOMETHING THAT DEFINES US.
BUT SOMETHING THAT INSPIRES US
TO BE BETTER, TO BE MORE
COMPASSIONATE AND MORE HUMBLE
PEOPLE.
>> WHAT HE SAID IS THAT HE
SIMPLY WANTED PEOPLE TO BE ABLE
TO BECOME MORE TOLERANT, TO BE
MORE HUMANE.
HE IS HOPING THAT THIS IS GOING
TO BE AN EVENT WHERE PEOPLE LOOK
NOT AT THE SHOOTER, NOT AT THE
CRIME ITSELF BUT IN TRYING TO
BECOME BETTER PEOPLE FOR THE
GREATER GOOD OF SOCIETY.
IT'S REALLY, TRULY REMARKABLE,
THIS FATHER CAME HERE EIGHT
MONTHS AGO WITH HIS FAMILY TO
THIS SMALL COMMUNITY TO TAKE A
JOB AT A NEONATAL SECTION OF THE
LOCAL HOSPITAL HERE.
HE'S HERE TO TRY TO HELP
CHILDREN GET BETTER AND YET HIS
CHILD WAS LOST DUE TO GUN
VIOLENCE.
IN THE FACE OF UNSPEAKABLE LOSS,
DON, FOR HIM TO BE ABLE TO STEP
OUTSIDE OF THAT AND ENCOURAGE
PEOPLE AND TO TALK ABOUT THESE
ISSUES REALLY IS SIMPLY
STUNNING.
>> SUCH A BEAUTIFUL FAMILY IN
THAT PHOTO AND REALLY SUCH A
COMPOSED MAN CONSIDERING WHAT
HAPPENED.
KYUNG LAH, THANK YOU VERY MUCH
FOR THAT.
WANT TO TALK ABOUT VICTORIA
SOTO, SHE ADORED HER STUDENTS
CALLING THEM HER KIDS.
WHEN THE SHOOTING STARTED, SHE
DID WHAT SHE COULD TO PROTECT
THEM.
TONIGHT, RESIDENTS OF STRATFORD,
CONNECTICUT, REMEMBERED HER.
PEOPLE AT A CANDLELIGHT VIGIL
WORE GREEN.
THE 27-YEAR-OLD'S FAVORITE
COLOR.
SHE TAUGHT FIRST GRADE AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
CNN'S JASON CARROLL JOINS ME NOW
WITH MORE ON THAT VIGIL.
HOW IS THIS COMMUNITY DEALING
WITH THIS EXTRAORDINARY LOSS
RIGHT NOW?
>> THEY'RE JUST COMPLETELY TORN
UP.
THERE'S NO OTHER WAY TO SAY IT,
TO SEE THE NUMBER OF PEOPLE,
HUNDREDS WHO CAME OUT HERE AT
STRATFORD HIGH SCHOOL.
THIS IS WHERE VICTORIA, VICKI AS
EVERYONE CALLED HER, VICKI SOTO,
THIS IS WHERE SHE GRADUATED BACK
IN 2003.
WHEN EVERYONE GOT TOGETHER HERE
TONIGHT, THEY DID THEIR BEST TO
REMEMBER HER.
THEY TALKED ABOUT HOW SOTO
ALWAYS WANTED TO BE A TEACHER,
EVER SINCE SHE WAS A LITTLE
GIRL.
SHE TALKED ABOUT WANTING TO BE A
TEACHER, THAT'S WHAT HER FRIENDS
SAID.
TONIGHT THEY TALKED ABOUT THE
HEROIC ACTIONS THAT SHE TOOK IN
HER CLASSROOM WHEN THE GUNMAN
BURST THROUGH THE DOOR, HOW SHE
RUSHED THE KIDS INTO A CLOSET TO
TRY AND SAVE THEM AND THEN OF
COURSE THE GUNMAN TOOK HER LIFE.
AS WE WERE OUT HERE TONIGHT WITH
HER SISTERS AND HER BROTHER, HER
COUSINS AND ALL OF HER FRIENDS,
AND DOING WHAT THEY CAN TO
REMEMBER HER, I SPOKE TO ONE
YOUNG WOMAN, A FRIEND OF SOTO'S
FOR MANY, MANY YEARS.
JUST LISTEN TO HOW SHE STRUGGLED
TO TALK ABOUT HOW SHE WILL
REMEMBER HER.
>> SHE WAS ALWAYS AT THE HOUSE
SMILING.
SHE DROVE US TO CHEERLEADING
PRACTICES A COUPLE OF TIMES.
I'M ALSO A TEACHER AND I CAN'T
EVEN IMAGINE GOING THROUGH WHAT
SHE WENT THROUGH.
I THINK HER PUTTING HERSELF OUT
THERE -- SHE'S JUST AN ANGEL AND
SHE JUST WENT STRAIGHT INTO
HEAVEN.
THERE'S NO DOUBT ABOUT THAT.
>> DON, THE REASON WHY SOTO'S
FAMILY DECIDED TO HOLD THIS
VIGIL TONIGHT, THE REASON WHY
THEY SHOWED UP AND GAVE US
PICTURES, PICTURES BY THE WAY
THAT SOTO'S MOTHER PICKED OUT
BECAUSE THEY WERE HER FAVORITE
PICTURES.
THE REASON WHY THEY DID ALL THIS
IS BECAUSE THEY DID NOT WANT
SOTO TO BE REMEMBERED AS JUST A
VICTIM.
THEY WANTED HER TO BE REMEMBERED
AS A DEDICATED TEACHER, A LOVING
DAUGHTER, A LOVING SISTER.
AT ONE POINT HER SISTER, CARLEY,
SHE STOOD UP AND SPOKE TO
EVERYONE WHO CAME OUT HERE TODAY
AND SHE SAID THE WORDS THAT SHE
HAD TWEETED EARLIER TODAY.
SHE SAID, HUG YOUR LOVED ONES,
TELL THEM HOW MUCH YOU LOVE THEM
BECAUSE YOU NEVER KNOW WHEN YOU
WILL EVER SEE THEM AGAIN.
THESE WERE THE WORDS SPOKEN BY
HER YOUNGER SISTER, 19-YEAR-OLD
CARLEY.
THIS IS HOW THEY WANT HER
REMEMBERED.
DON?
>> JASON, YOU ARE EXACTLY RIGHT.
THESE ARE NOT JUST VICTIMS.
THEY'RE EXTRAORDINARY PEOPLE WHO
HAVE LED EXTRAORDINARY LIVES AND
TAKEN AWAY WAY TOO SOON.
JASON CARROLL, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH FOR THAT REPORT.
WITNESSES SAY THE FIRST SHOTS
RANG OUT YESTERDAY JUST AFTER
THE MORNING ANNOUNCEMENTS WERE
BEING READ AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
POLICE ARE TRYING TO HAMMER DOWN
EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED BEFORE
THAT MOMENT.
AND OUR TOM FOREMAN HAS A
BREAKDOWN ON WHAT INVESTIGATORS
KNOW SO FAR.
>> POLICE ARE SEARCHING OVER AN
IMMENSE AREA FOR ANY CLUE WHY
THIS HAPPENED.
THEY'VE SEARCHED THE BROTHER'S
APARTMENT DOWN HERE IN NEW
JERSEY.
THEY BELIEVE THE GUNMAN WENT
DIRECTLY HERE AFTER HIS MOTHER'S
MURDER AND EMERGED FROM HIS CAR
IN THE PARKING LOT CARRYING
WEAPONS VERY MUCH LIKE THESE.
BUT WHAT HAPPENED THEN?
LET'S LOOK AT THE TIME LINE
BASED ON POLICE RADIO REPORTS
AND EYEWITNESSES.
9:30 IN THE MORNING, THAT'S WHEN
WE BELIEVE THAT HE EMERGED FROM
HIS CAR AND HEADED INTO THE
SCHOOL HERE.
WE DON'T KNOW THAT THIS IS HIS
CAR.
BUT THEY'VE PAID A LOT OF
ATTENTION TO THIS VEHICLE OVER
THE PAST FEW DAYS.
HERE IS WHERE HE ENCOUNTERED HIS
FIRST BARRICADE BECAUSE THERE
WAS A SECURITY SYSTEM ON THE
DOORS THERE RECENTLY PUT IN BY
THE PRINCIPAL, WHERE HE WOULD
HAVE TO BE BUZZED IN.
POLICE LATER FOUND THAT THE
GLASS HERE HAD BEEN SHOT OUT OR
BROKEN OUT IN SOME FASHION.
THAT SEEMS TO BE HOW HE ENTERED
THE SCHOOL.
WHAT HAPPENED AFTER THAT?
WELL, THE FIRST CALL TO THE
POLICE THAT SAID THERE WAS A
PROBLEM CAME AT 9:36.
THE FIRST CALL SAYING THERE IS
GUNFIRE INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
OBVIOUSLY PEOPLE IN THE SCHOOL
KNEW IT BECAUSE THEY COULD
EITHER HEAR IT DIRECTLY OR
BECAUSE THEY HEARD IT OVER THE
SCHOOL'S P.A. SYSTEM, THERE WERE
ANNOUNCEMENTS BEING MADE AT THE
TIME.
ALL THE SHOOTING TOOK PLACE IN A
A VERY SMALL AREA UP IN THIS
PART OF THE SCHOOL.
IT WAS IMPORTANT THAT EVERYBODY
ELSE HAVE SOME IDEA THAT THIS
WAS GOING ON SO THEY COULD TRY
TO BE SAFE IN THESE
CIRCUMSTANCES.
BEYOND THAT, WHAT HAPPENED?
AT 9:38, POLICE WERE SAYING
ALREADY THEY WERE HEARING
REPORTS THAT THE SHOOTING WAS
OVER.
AN INCREDIBLY SHORT PERIOD OF
TIME.
2, 2 1/2 MINUTES, MAYBE, WHERE
THE BULK, IF NOT ALL OF THE
SHOOTING TOOK PLACE.
WHAT WAS THE NEXT PHASE OF ALL
OF THIS?
THE NEXT PHASE CAME WHEN AT
ABOUT 9:40, POLICE AT THE SCHOOL
SAID, WE NEED SOME EMERGENCY
MEDICAL SERVICES HERE.
THAT WAS THE FIRST CALL FOR
AMBULANCES.
IT WAS FOR TWO AMBULANCES TO
BEGIN WITH AND THEN AS THEY
REALIZED THEY HAD MANY MORE
VICTIMS IN A MATTER OF MINUTES,
THERE WAS A CALL FOR MANY, MANY
MORE EMERGENCY MEDICAL
TECHNICIANS AND AMBULANCES TO
COME TO THE SCHOOL.
AND THEN SURPRISINGLY, BY 9:50
IN THE MORNING, POLICE WERE
ESSENTIALLY SAYING THAT THEY HAD
A SUSPECT WHO WAS DOWN, MEANING
THEY HAD HAD ONE SUSPECT WHO IS
DEAD, THEY HAD SECURED THE
BUILDING TO SOME DEGREE.
THEY'D CLEARED THE BUILDING IS
THE LANGUAGE THEY USED.
AND A LOT OF THE KIDS WERE BEING
LED AWAY.
THIS IS A PICTURE FROM "THE
NEWTOWN BEE" OF THE KIDS BEING
LED AWAY.
THIS IS A VERY SHORT PERIOD OF
TIME, FROM 17 TO 20 MINUTES THAT
THIS WENT FROM NOTHING HAPPENING
TO ALL OF THESE EVENTS HAPPENING
THAT HAVE CHANGED THE LIVES OF
SO MANY PEOPLE.
AND POLICE WILL CONTINUE GOING
OVER AND OVER AND OVER AGAIN THE
DETAILS OF THE MOVEMENT OF THIS
SHOOTER AND HIS VICTIMS TO TRY
TO GET A BETTER UNDERSTANDING OF
PRECISELY HOW IT ALL HAPPENED.
>> TOM, THANKS.
WHAT HAPPENED IN THAT BUILDING
AFFECTED EVERYONE.
THE TRAGEDY IS TOUGH FOR THE
ENTIRE COMMUNITY HERE.
AND THOSE NOT DIRECTLY AFFECTED
STILL WANT TO MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
EARLIER, I SPOKE WITH TWO WOMEN
TRYING TO DO JUST THAT.
WHEN YOU CAME UP TO TALK TO ME,
YOU LADIES COULD BARELY GET THE
WORDS OUT.
>> THIS IS -- THERE ARE NO
WORDS.
THERE ARE NO WORDS.
AND EVEN RIGHT NOW, WE KNOW THAT
FAMILIES ARE CRYING TOGETHER,
TRYING TO GET THROUGH DAY TO
DAY.
AND WE FEEL THAT SINCE WE
WEREN'T DIRECTLY IMPACTED, WE
FEEL LIKE WE WANT TO BE ABLE TO
USE OUR VOICES TO SAY THINGS
THAT WE KNOW THAT PEOPLE ARE
GOING TO BE SAYING FOR A LONG
TIME AFTER THE CAMERAS ARE GONE.
AND SOMETIMES IT'S AFTER THE
CAMERAS ARE GONE THAT THINGS
STOP WORKING.
AND MOTION STOPS.
>> FOR YOU, YOU'VE BEEN CRYING
THE ENTIRE TIME YOU'RE STANDING
HERE.
>> THERE ARE NO WORDS.
THERE ARE NO ADEQUATE WORDS TO
DESCRIBE WHAT HAS HAPPENED HERE
AND HOW CHILDREN AND PARENTS AND
GRANDPARENTS AND UNCLES AND
AUNTS AND PEOPLE WHO LIVE FAR
AWAY WHO JUST KNOW THAT WE ARE
HERE, THERE ARE NO WORDS.
AND THIS CAN HAPPEN TO ANYONE
ANYWHERE.
WE NEED TO MAKE OUR CHILDREN
FEEL SAFE TO GO BACK TO SCHOOL.
AND I WANT TO KNOW HOW WE CAN DO
THAT.
I WANT SOMEONE TO GIVE US AN
ANSWER TO THIS QUESTION.
>> BY YOU ASKING, SOME OF THOSE
QUESTIONS MAY BE ANSWERED.
AND YOU ARE MAKING A DIFFERENCE.
YOU ARE HELPING.
>> WE HOPE SO.
>> THANK YOU.
HOW OLD ARE YOUR KIDS?
>> I HAVE AN 11 AND 14-YEAR-OLD.
>> WHAT GRADES?
>> SIXTH AND NINTH.
>> ARE YOU GOING TO SEND THEM TO
SCHOOL?
>> I'M GOING TO SEND THEM TO
SCHOOL AS LONG AS I CAN TELL
THEM THAT SOMEBODY IS DOING
SOMETHING DIFFERENT TO MAKE THEM
FEEL SAFE.
>> HOW OLD ARE YOUR KIDS?
>> MY DAUGHTER IS 11 AND MY SON
IS 8.
>> ARE YOU GOING TO SEND THEM TO
SCHOOL?
>> IF I FEEL THAT THEY'RE SAFE,
IF I FEEL THAT THEY'RE SAFE.
>> THANK YOU.
>> IT'S JUST UNBELIEVABLE.
I'M SO SORRY.
THANK YOU.
>> I THINK THAT'S ALL, THANK
YOU.
>> CAN I HAVE THIS NOTE FOR
EVERY PARENT?
>> YEAH.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR THE KIND
OF COVERAGE THAT YOU'RE --
YOU'VE BEEN VERY SENSITIVE.
>> THOSE WOMEN DIDN'T WANT THEIR
FACES ON CAMERA.
THEY SAID WE COULD SHOOT THEM
FROM THE SIDE BECAUSE THEY HAD
BEEN CRYING ALL DAY.
THE REASON THEY CAME HERE, THEY
SAID THEY WERE WATCHING THE
BROADCAST EARLIER AND I ASKED,
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN TO YOUR
CHILDREN, WHAT DO YOU DO NEXT?
AND THIS IS THE NOTE THAT THEY
WROTE TO ME BEFORE THEY WALKED
AWAY.
I SAID, PLEASE LET ME PUT IT ON
CAMERA.
THEY SAID, EARLIER YOU ASKED
SOMEONE BEING INTERVIEWED WHAT
WE WOULD WANT OUR COUNTRY TO DO
FOR OUR COMMUNITY.
THIS IS WHAT WE WOULD LIKE.
RIGHT AWAY, WE NEED SPECIFIC
PLANS AND ACTIONS TO IMPROVE
SAFETY FOR OUR CHILDREN AND OUR
SCHOOLS BEFORE THEY'RE EXPECTED
TO RETURN TO SCHOOL.
WE FEEL WE COULD BETTER ENSURE
OUR CHILDREN'S SAFETY BY PLACING
A PERMANENT OFFICER IN EACH OF
OUR SCHOOLS IN NEWTOWN SO THEY
WILL KNOW THAT SOMEONE IS THERE
FOR THE PURPOSE OF PROTECTING
THEIR SCHOOL AND THEN THEY WENT
ON SAYING WHAT ELSE THEY WOULD
LIKE.
BASICALLY THEY WANT TO MAKE SURE
THAT THEIR KIDS ARE SAFE WHEN
THEY GO TO SCHOOL.
THEY SAID THEIR KIDS ARE ASKING
THEM QUESTIONS THAT THEY CAN'T
ANSWER AND THEY'RE AFRAID TO GO
BACK TO SCHOOL IN THE COMING
WEEKS.
A LOT OF PARENTS REALLY ARE
ASKING THOSE QUESTIONS RIGHT
NOW.
I THOUGHT IT WAS IMPORTANT TO
GET THEM ON, PUT THEM ON CAMERA
AND LET THEIR VOICES BE HEARD.
TONIGHT, A LOT OF PARENTS
WATCHING THESE EVENTS AT HOME,
WHILE THEIR HEARTS ACHE FOR
THEIR FAMILIES, THEY HAVE TO BE
WORRIED, THEY HAVE TO BE
WORRIED.
COULD IT HAPPEN HERE?
WE'RE GOING TO LOOK AT SCHOOL
SAFETY IN A MOMENT.
ALSO A YOUNG MAN WHO RAN TO THE
SCHOOL WHEN HE HEARD THE SHOTS.
HIS STORY IS NEXT.
[ Woman ] DEAR CAT, YOUR HAIR
MIXES WITH POLLEN AND DUST.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
>>> I WANT TO GIVE YOU A QUICK
UPDATE NOW ON TODAY'S
DEVELOPMENTS HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
TOMORROW WILL NO DOUBT BE
ANOTHER EMOTIONAL DAY HERE.
THE PRESIDENT IS COMING TO MEET
WITH THE VICTIMS' FAMILIES.
HE'S ALSO GOING TO BE ATTEND AN
INTERFAITH VIGIL SCHEDULED FOR
TOMORROW EVENING.
THE SHOOTER'S FATHER RELEASED A
STATEMENT TONIGHT.
THE FATHER'S NAME IS PETER
LANZA.
HE SAYS, WORDS CANNOT EXPRESS
HIS FAMILY'S HEARTBREAK.
HE SAYS THE FAMILY IS IN WHAT HE
CALLS A STATE OF DISBELIEF.
SIX WOMEN, 20 CHILDREN DIED AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
THAT NUMBER INCLUDES 12 GIRLS
AND EIGHT BOYS.
16 OF THE KIDS WERE ONLY 6 YEARS
OLD.
THE OTHERS HAD TURNED 7 IN JUST
THE LAST FEW MONTHS.
I WANT TO BRING IN NOW A STUDENT
AT NEWTOWN HIGH SCHOOL.
HE JOINS ME NOW
YOU ACTUALLY RAN INTO THE SCHOOL
WHEN YOU HEARD THE SHOTS.
YOU STAYED HOME FROM SCHOOL THAT
DAY BY HAPPENSTANCE.
YOU RAN INTO THE SCHOOL.
WHAT HAPPENED?
>> I DID NOT ACTUALLY RUN INTO
THE SCHOOL BUT I WAS VERY CLOSE
TO THE PERIMETER OF THE SCHOOL
AND THAT'S WHERE -- AS SOON AS I
ENTERED THE DRIVEWAY OF THE
SCHOOL, WE SAW A LOT OF POLI
CARS THERE.
>> YOU WERE AT HOME.
DID YOU HEAR SHOTS?
WHAT DID YOU --
>> WELL, MY NEIGHBOR CALLED US
CLAIMING SHE HEARD SHOTS.
AND THAT'S WHEN WE HEARD A LOT
OF SIRENS GOING OFF.
AND THAT'S WHEN WE GOT VERY
CONCERNED BECAUSE THE SCHOOL DID
NOT PICK UP THE PHONE.
WE CALLED THE SCHOOL.
THEY DID NOT PICK UP THE PHONE.
THAT WAS WHEN WE REALLY BECAME
CONCERNED.
>> ONCE YOU GOT THERE, YOU SAID
YOU GOT TO THE PERIMETER OF THE
SCHOOL.
>> RIGHT.
>> ONCE YOU GOT THERE, THEN
WHAT?
>> THEN IT WAS JUST HORRIFYING.
WITHIN A MATTER OF THREE
MINUTES, WE SAW TWO STUDENTS
BEING CARRIED OUT BY STATE
TROOPERS.
THEY WERE NOT MOVING.
THEY WERE VERY PALE AND IT WAS
JUST A VERY HORRIFYING SCENE.
AND THEN A THIRD FEMALE CAME
OUT.
SHE HAD A LOT OF BLOOD OVER HER
FACE.
IT WAS JUST HORRIBLE.
IT WAS BLOOD SPLATTER FROM OTHER
STUDENTS WAS MY GUESS BECAUSE
SHE WAS WALKING FINE.
>> THESE ARE YOUNG PEOPLE THAT
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT, 5, 6, 7
YEARS OLD.
>> YEAH, NO MORE THAN THAT.
IT WAS HORRIBLE.
>> DID YOU FEEL HELPLESS IN NOT
BEING ABLE TO DO ANYTHING?
>> YOU KNOW, I THINK THAT'S THE
BEST WORD TO DESCRIBE IT.
HELPLESS.
I WAS WAITING FOR MY SISTER.
IT WAS 20 MINUTES BETWEEN THE
TIME I SAW THOSE OTHER
FEMALES --
>> YOUR SISTER GOES TO THE
SCHOOL?
>> YES, SHE DOES.
>> YOU DIDN'T KNOW --
>> I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT WAS
HAPPENING TO HER.
>> YOUR SISTER IS 7?
>> SHE'S 9.
>> SHE'S 9?
>> CORRECT.
>> NOT KNOWING IN THOSE
MOMENTS --
>> IT WAS HORRIBLE.
THOUGHTS WERE RUNNING THROUGH MY
HEAD, ALL MY MEMORIES WITH HER
WERE RUNNING THROUGH MY HEAD
DURING THOSE 20 MINUTES.
IT SEEMED LIKE DAYS.
BUT IT WAS HORRIFYING.
>> WHEN DID SHE COME OUT?
>> SHE CAME OUT ABOUT 20 MINUTES
AFTER THE -- I SAW THE OTHER
STUDENTS -- THE TWO OTHER
STUDENTS THAT UNFORTUNATELY WERE
PRONOUNCED DEAD LATER ON.
AND THE STUDENTS -- ALL THE
STUDENTS WERE CRYING AND
SOBBING.
AND THEY WERE JUST -- THEY WERE
TRAUMATIZED.
>> HOW'S YOUR SISTER DOING?
>> SHE'S DOING WELL.
AGAIN, SHE'S VERY TRAUMATIZED
NATURALLY.
BUT I CREDIT THE TEACHERS FOR
KEEPING THEM CALM.
THEY'RE VERY HEROIC TEACHERS
THAT DAY.
THE PRINCIPAL, THERE WERE
MULTIPLE TEACHERS THAT DID A
FANTASTIC JOB KEEPING THE
CHILDREN CALM.
>> WHAT DID YOUR SISTER SAY?
DID SHE HEAR ANYTHING --
>> YEAH.
THE FIRST THING SHE TOLD ME WAS
THAT SHE HAD HEARD THE INTERCOM
SYSTEM COME ON AND THROUGH THE
INTERCOM, SHE HEARD SCREAMS AND
BULLETS -- SHE HEARD THE
GUNSHOTS AND THE SCREAMS
OCCURRING IN THE MAIN OFFICE OF
THE BUILDING.
THAT'S ULTIMATELY WHEN THE
SCHOOL WENT INTO LOCKDOWN.
>> A 9-YEAR-OLD.
CAN YOU IMAGINE A 9-YEAR-OLD
HAVING TO DEAL WITH THAT?
I JUST CAN'T.
>> IT'S TRAUMATIC.
>> TELL US -- TALK TO OUR
VIEWERS AND EVERYONE WHO'S
WATCHING HERE ABOUT HOW YOU GUYS
ARE DOING, YOUR SISTER, YOUR
FAMILY, THE COMMUNITY?
>> FIRST OFF, I'D REALLY LIKE TO
GIVE MY CONDOLENCES TO EVERYONE
WHO'S SUFFERING FROM THIS,
FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS, IT'S AN
ABSOLUTE TRAGEDY.
BUT I HAVE A LOT OF CONFIDENCE
IN NEWTOWN.
CULTURALLY WE'RE A VERY, VERY
STRONG TOWN.
AND WE STICK TOGETHER.
WE'RE A TIGHT-KNIT COMMUNITY.
I KNOW WE'RE GOING TO WORK
THROUGH THIS.
EVERYONE CARES ABOUT EVERYONE.
AND THAT'S JUST WHO WE ARE.
THAT'S OUR CULTURE.
>> YOU'RE 17?
>> YES.
>> THE SHOOTER IS 20.
DID YOU KNOW HIM?
>> NO.
BUT UPON HEARING HE WAS 20, I
WAS SHOCKED.
I WAS LOST FOR WORDS.
HOW COULD SOMEONE SO YOUNG
COMMIT SUCH A HEINOUS ACT.
>> YOU DON'T KNOW HIS FAMILY?
>> I DO NOT.
I DO NOT.
>> THANK YOU.
I APPRECIATE IT.
>> WE'RE GLAD YOUR SISTER IS
OKAY.
AGAIN, OUR THOUGHTS AND PRAYERS
ARE WITH EVERYONE HERE.
>> THANK YOU.
>> APPRECIATE IT.
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING JUST TO
WATCH THIS COMMUNITY IN THE
COMING DAYS TRY TO DEAL WITH
THIS, TO SEE HOW THEY'RE GOING
TO COPE, HOW THE WORLD IS GOING
TO TRY TO HELP THEM GET THROUGH
IT, WHAT WORDS OF COMFORT THE
PRESIDENT WILL OFFER THEM AS
WELL.
WE'LL BE HERE TO COVER IT FOR
YOU HERE ON CNN.
A LITTLE WHILE AGO, I TOOK A
WALK THROUGH THIS TOWN, THIS
TOWN OF JUST 27,000 PEOPLE, ALL
OF THEM STILL TRYING TO PROCESS
THE HORROR OF WHAT HAPPENED JUST
DOWN THE ROAD.
RIGHT BEHIND ME, THAT'S THE ROAD
THAT LEADS UP TO THE SCHOOL
WHERE THIS HAPPENED.
IT HAS BEEN BLOCKED OFF.
YOU CAN SEE THE SIGN HERE RIGHT
ACROSS THE STREET ON THAT PORCH,
IT SAYS, GOD BLESS SANDY HOOK.
THAT JUST ABOUT SAYS IT ALL
AND RIGHT HERE IN THE MIDDLE OF
THE SQUARE, 26 CANDLES FOR ALL
OF THE VICTIMS IN THIS TRAGEDY
RIGHT HERE AT THE TIME SQUARE.
AND UP THE STREET, A CHURCH
WHERE THE VICTIMS ARE BEING
MEMORIALIZED.
THIS IS ONE OF THE INTIMATE
LITTLE SQUARES HERE IN SANDY
HOOK.
YOU CAN SEE THE LITTLE QUAINT
STORES, BEAUTIFUL LITTLE STORES.
AND THEN COME THIS WAY, YOU CAN
SEE JUST THE MEDIA.
AND PEOPLE HAVE TAKEN THIS
SQUARE OVER.
WHEN I TALK TO PEOPLE HERE, THEY
SAY, THERE'S NEVER THIS MANY
PEOPLE.
THERE ARE NEVER THIS MANY PEOPLE
WHO COME TO THIS TOWN ON A
SATURDAY OR SUNDAY.
TO SEE HOW INTIMATE AND
BEAUTIFUL THIS TOWN IS, LOOK, A
CREEK THAT RUNS RIGHT THROUGH
IT.
THE PEOPLE OF THIS SMALL TOWN
PROBABLY NEVER DREAMED THAT
THEIR TOWN WOULD BE THE FOCUS OF
SUCH PAIN AND ANGUISH AND
SORROW.
THIS IS THE NEWTOWN UNITED
METHODIST CHURCH AND WHERE A LOT
OF THE MEDIA ARE CAMPED OUT.
THEY GIVE PRESCHOOL CLASSES,
AGES TWO TO SIX, SADLY SOME OF
THOSE KIDS HAVE DIED
THERE'S THE CHURCH BEHIND ME.
IT'S BEEN OPENED NOW FOR 24
HOURS.
IT'S GOING TO BE OPEN 24 HOURS
FOR AS LONG AS THEY NEED IT
HERE.
SOME OF THE MEMBERS OF THAT
CHURCH DIED AND ANYONE WHO WANTS
TO COME BY AND PAY THEIR
RESPECTS TO THE PEOPLE WHO DIED,
ANYONE WHO NEEDS HELP FROM THIS
CHURCH, THEY CAN COME HERE AND
GET IT.
AFTER THIS SHOOTING INSIDE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, THE
SAFETY ISSUE WILL NOW BE FRONT
AND CENTER AT SCHOOLS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY.
DO CLASSROOMS NEED TO BE CHANGED
INTO PANIC ROOMS OR AS I'VE BEEN
SAYING EARLIER, CAN WE MAKE
CLASSROOMS INTO MINI PRISONS?
IT SEEMS LIKE WHAT WE MAY HAVE
TO MAKE OUR SCHOOLS IN ORDER TO
BE SAFE.
I WANT TO BRING IN LOU PALUMBO.
HE IS A FORMER POLICE OFFICER
AND NOW THE DIRECTOR OF A LEAD
INTELLIGENCE BASED SECURITY FIRM
SOME SCHOOLS ALREADY HAVE
ROAMING OFFICERS, METAL
DETECTORS, OFFICERS ROAMING THE
HALLWAYS.
WHAT CAN WE DO TO MAKE OUR
SCHOOLS SAFER?
DO WE NEED ALL OF THESE MEASURES
IN PLACE?
>> WELL, APPARENTLY BASED ON
THIS INCIDENT THAT TOOK PLACE UP
HERE YESTERDAY, I GUESS YOU
COULD SUPPORT THAT ARGUMENT.
IT'S JUST UNFORTUNATE TO THINK
THAT WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO
CREATE ENVIRONMENTS FOR OUR
CHILDREN TO LEARN IN THAT ARE A
BIT MORE SECURE.
AND I DON'T THINK MY
RECOMMENDATIONS ARE ANYTHING
THAT ARE EXTREME.
I MENTIONED TO YOU EARLIER, DON,
ONE THING I WOULD DO IS LOCK
THESE CLASSROOM DOORS.
I WOULD CHANGE THE DOORS AND
FORTIFY THE LOCKS AND UPGRADE
THEM.
THE SAME ON ENTERING THE
BUILDING.
THERE'S A CONDITION WHAT WE CALL
A MANTRAP.
THAT'S WHEN YOU ENTER FROM AN
OUTER DOOR INTO A TYPE OF FOYER
AREA WHERE THERE'S ANOTHER DOOR
AND THAT DOOR IS SECURED UNTIL
THEY'RE COMFORTABLE WITH WHO YOU
ARE.
YOU KNOW THERE IS A LOT OF
THINGS THEY CAN IMPLEMENT
I THINK WE NEED TO ADDRESS
BIGGER ISSUES THAT ARE NOT JUST
IMPACTING OUR EDUCATIONAL
INSTITUTIONS BUT OUR ENTIRE
COUNTRY.
IT HAS TO DO WITH YOUR SAFETY,
OUR PEACE OF MIND.
OUR FEELING OF HOW SECURE WE
REALLY ARE
>> I DON'T KNOW IF YOU GOT A
CHANCE TO HEAR THE TWO MOTHERS
THATCAME UP AND WROTE ME THE
LETTER ABOUT WHAT THEY SAY TO
THEIR KIDS.
THEY SAY, OUR KIDS ARE ASKING
ALL THOSE QUESTIONS.
WE DON'T HAVE THE ANSWERS.
THEY'RE ASKING US ABOUT GOING
BACK TO SCHOOL ON MONDAY.
HOW DO YOU REASSURE PARENTS AND
EVEN STUDENTS THAT THEY'RE SAFE
AT SCHOOL?
CAN YOU REASSURE THEM?
CAN YOU BE SURE OF THAT?
>> APPARENTLY YOU CANNOT.
WHAT I WOULD DO IN THE
TRANSITIONAL PERIOD IN
PARTICULAR FOR THESE CHILDREN UP
HERE, I WOULD HAVE SOME TYPE OF
UNIFORM LAW ENFORCEMENT PRESENCE
TO EASE THEM THROUGH A
TRANSITION OF COMFORT AGAIN TO
WHERE THEY CAN START TO RELAX
AND FEEL A BIT MORE SECURE AND A
BIT MORE SAFE.
AND WATCHED OVER, SO TO SPEAK
I DON'T THINK THE GRAVITY OF
THIS SITUATION FOR ALL OF US HAS
SET IN YET, NOT IN THIS
COMMUNITY AND NOT IN THIS
NATION.
I DON'T THINK PEOPLE REALLY HAVE
THOUGHT THIS THROUGH WHAT THE
ANGUISH WAS FOR THESE BABIES IN
THAT CLASSROOM.
IT'S A LITTLE DISTURBING TO EVEN
SPEAK ABOUT IT.
>> THAT THIS HAPPENS -- I SAID
AMAZING EARLIER, AND THE
PERPLEXING SENSE OF THAT WORD
THAT EVERY TIME WE HEAR ABOUT
THIS, WE SAY, YOU KNOW, THE
COMMUNITY'S RESILIENT.
THEY'LL GET THROUGH IT.
WE SHOULDN'T BE HAVING TO SAY
THAT.
>> WITHOUT QUESTION.
AND WE SHOULDN'T BE BURYING
CHILDREN AT THIS AGE.
IT'S SYMPTOMATIC OF A MUCH
LARGER PROBLEM IN OUR COUNTRY.
>> I WENT ON THE AIR I THINK IT
WAS ABOUT 11:40 ON FRIDAY AND I
WAS TALKING TO YOU ABOUT SAFETY
AND SECURITY.
AND I SAID, LOU, YOU SEND YOUR
KIDS OFF TO SCHOOL AND THIS IS
THE WORST PHONE CALL THAT YOU
CAN GET.
THEN WE THOUGHT MAYBE IT WAS
JUST SOME ANGRY PARENT OR
SOMEONE WHO HAD JUST COME IN AND
THAT WAS THE ONLY PERSON
INVOLVED.
AND THEN AN HOUR LATER, WE FIND
OUT IT'S 20 CHILDREN INVOLVED IN
THIS SHOOTING.
WE HAVE TO STOP THIS.
WE HAVE TO LOOK AT MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES AND WE HAVE TO LOOK AT
GUN LAWS IN THIS COUNTRY.
>> WE HAVE TO ADDRESS THIS
INTERPRETATION WE HAVE OF THE
CONSTITUTION.
AND I WOULD SAY INTERJECT SOME
LEVEL OF COMMON SENSE, DECENCY
AND SENSIBILITY.
NO ONE'S OPPOSED TO IS SECOND
AMENDMENT.
I'M CERTAINLY NOT.
A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE.
>> I THINK WHEN PEOPLE SEE US DO
THIS -- THEY SAY, NO ONE'S
TRYING TO DO THAT.
IT'S SOMETHING PEOPLE ARE TRYING
TO MAKE AN ISSUE OF.
LET'S REALLY TALK ABOUT THIS,
LOU.
WE DON'T COVER MULTIPLE
STABBINGS WHERE 20 PEOPLE -- 26
PEOPLE DIE IN A SCHOOL.
WE DON'T COVER WHERE MOLOTOV
COCKTAIL GOES OFF IN THE SCHOOL
OR ANYTHING OF THAT NATURE.
IT'S USUALLY FROM SOMEONE WITH
SOME TYPE OF ASSAULT WEAPON AND
SOMEONE WHO HAS A SICK MIND WHO
GOES IN AND DOES THESE SORTS OF
THINGS.
>> THE REAL UNFORTUNATE PART IS
COUPLED WITH A SICK MIND OR
DERANGEMENT OR DELUSION, WE HAVE
A VEHICLE OF DELIVERY OF THEIR
MESSAGE.
THAT'S WHERE THE FIREARM COMES
IN.
WHAT WE SPOKE TO EARLIER IS
KNOWING A BIT MORE ABOUT THE
PEOPLE WE'RE PUTTING THESE
FIREARMS IN THE HANDS OF.
TALKING ABOUT JUST SCREENING
PEOPLE PSYCHOLOGICALLY.
THIS IS NOT AN ANOMALY.
THIS IS BECOMING A PATTERN.
ALTHOUGH THEY WOULD LIKE TO
STATISTICALLY ADDRESS THIS BY
SAYING THE NUMBER OF TIMES OR
THE PERCENTAGE OF THESE
INCIDENTS IN DIRECT PROPORTION
TO OUR POPULATION ARE .5%.
THAT'S A GREAT STATISTIC UNLESS
IT'S YOUR CHILD.
BUT THERE ARE WAYS WE CAN DO
THIS.
I THINK WHAT WE HAVE TO DO IS
TAKE THE POLITICAL ASPECT OF
THIS THING OUT AND SIT DOWN THE
PEOPLE WHO HAVE THE ABILITY TO
CHANGE THE WAY WE'RE ADDRESSING
THIS.
THIS IS A DISGUSTING PROBLEM
THAT WE'RE DEALING WITH --
>> AND IT'S SOMETHING THAT WE
HAVE TO DEAL WITH.
THANK YOU.
>> WITHOUT QUESTION.
>> AND AS YOU SAY, TAKE THE
POLITICS OUT OF IT.
IT'S A COMMONSENSE ISSUE, NOT A
LEFT/RIGHT ISSUE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
MOST OF US CAN'T EVEN IMAGINE
HOW THIS CAN HAPPEN.
BUT SOME PEOPLE CAN BECAUSE THEY
HAVE BEEN THROUGH IT BEFORE.
CNN'S JOSH LEVS TELLS US HOW
VICTIMS OF THE 1999 COLUMBINE
SHOOTING ARE REACTING TO THIS
HORROR.
>> MILLIONS OF PEOPLE ALL OVER
THE WORLD ARE MOURNING FOR THE
PEOPLE WHO WERE KILLED IN
CONNECTICUT.
BUT THERE'S A CERTAIN GROUP OF
PEOPLE IN THIS COUNTRY, A VERY
SMALL GROUP, FORTUNATELY, THAT
CAN ASSOCIATE IN A WAY THAT MOST
OF US CANNOT IMAGINE.
THESE ARE PEOPLE WHO KNOW WHAT
IT'S LIKE TO BE AT SCHOOL WHEN A
TYPICAL DAY TURNS INTO CARNAGE.
SOME OF THEM ARE SURVIVORS OF
THE COLUMBINE MASSACRE 14 YEARS
AGO, SOME OF WHOM ARE NOW
PARENTS THEMSELVES.
I SPOKE WITH ONE WHO'S NOW A
MOM, CASEY JOHNSON.
>> YOU LOSE THE SENSE THAT
THINGS COULD NEVER HAPPEN TO
YOU.
SO MANY PARENTS WOULD SAY, THIS
WOULD NEVER HAPPEN AT MY CHILD'S
SCHOOL.
FOR ME AS A PARENT OF A CHILD, I
BELIEVE THIS COULD EASILY HAPPEN
AT MY CHILD'S SCHOOL BECAUSE
THAT'S BECAUSE IT HAS HAPPENED
TO ME BEFORE.
I WOULD HOPE THAT THE PEOPLE
INVOLVED WILL WALK BESIDE THESE
CHILDREN AND THE FAMILIES FOR
THE YEARS TO COME.
THEY HAVE YEARS AND YEARS OF
HEALING THAT THEY'RE GOING TO BE
FACING.
AND I HOPE THAT WE CAN COME
BESIDE THEM AND ENCOURAGE THEM
AND FOCUS POSITIVELY ON THE
LIVES OF THE ONES THAT WERE
LOST.
>> I WANT YOU TO MEET SHAWN
GRAVES.
SHAWN WAS SHOT SIX TIMES AT
COLUMBINE.
HE ENDED UP SPENDING MORE THAN A
YEAR IN A WHEELCHAIR.
TO THIS DAY, HE HAS SOME PAIN
BECAUSE OF IT.
I SPOKE WITH HIM ABOUT HOW THE
NEWS FROM CONNECTICUT IS
AFFECTING HIM.
>> I LIVE WITH PAIN PHYSICALLY
ON A DAILY BASIS BECAUSE OF THE
INJURIES THAT I SUSTAINED.
BUT LOOKING BACK THEN, I TRY NOT
TO THINK ABOUT IT.
BUT WHEN SOMETHING LIKE THIS
HAPPENS, THAT'S THE FIRST THING
YOU DO.
YOU BEGIN TO RELIVE IT.
AND TURNING IT ON TO THE --
PUTTING ON THE NEWS AND JUST
WATCHING THE COVERAGE LIVE FROM
THIS POINT OF VIEW VERSUS WHERE
I WAS THEN, IT WILL TAKE YOU
THROUGH AN EMOTIONAL TOLL,
THAT'S FOR SURE.
>> AND A LOT OF THE SURVIVORS OF
COLUMBINE WERE ACTUALLY REACHING
OUT TO FAMILIES IN CONNECTICUT,
SOME OF THEM HAVE FORMED A GROUP
NOW THAT REACH OUT TO FAMILIES
AFTER MASS SHOOTINGS AND THEY
ARE JUST AMONG THE MANY AROUND
THE WORLD WHO ARE MOURNING IN
THE WAKE OF THIS TRAGEDY.
WE INVITE YOU TO SHARE YOUR
THOUGHTS, CONDOLENCES AT
iREPORT.COM.
>> JOSH, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
LET'S NOT FORGET THE FIRST
VICTIM OF THIS TRAGEDY HERE IN
NEWTOWN, THE MOTHER OF THE
SHOOTER.
NEXT, MORE ABOUT HER AND THE
WEAPONS THAT ENDED UP IN THE
HANDS OF HER TROUBLED SON.
Music is a universal language.
But when I was in an accident...
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
Information on my phone.
Connection to doctors who
get where I'm from.
And tools to estimate what
my care may cost.
So I never missed a beat.
We're more than 78,000
people looking out for
more than 70
million Americans.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.
>>> WE'LL HAVE MORE ON THE
SHOOTING IN JUST A MOMENT.
BUT FIRST, SOME OTHER STORIES
THAT WE'RE FOLLOWING AND
MONITORING FOR YOU HERE ON CNN,
INCLUDING AN ABOUTFACE BY HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER ON TAX
RATES.
A SOURCE TELLS CNN THAT FOR THE
FIRST TIME, THE HOUSE SPEAKER IS
OPEN TO RAISING RATES ON THE
WEALTHIEST AMERICANS TO AVOID
THE FISCAL CLIFF.
BUT HE WANTS HIGHER RATES TO
ONLY APPLY TO THOSE MAKING $1
MILLION A YEAR OR MORE.
PRESIDENT BARACK OBAMA WANTS
RATES TO RISE FOR THOSE MAKING
MORE THAN $250,000 A YEAR.
>>> IT LOOKS LIKE MASSACHUSETTS
SENATOR JOHN KERRY WILL BE
NOMINATED TO TAKE OVER FOR
HILLARY CLINTON AS THE STATE
DEPARTMENT.
A DEMOCRATIC SOURCE TELLS CNN,
PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS CHOSEN KERRY
FOR THE POST.
ON THURSDAY, U.N. AMBASSADOR
SUSAN RICE WITHDREW HER NAME
FROM CONSIDERATION FOR THAT JOB.
>>> HILLARY CLINTON MEANWHILE IS
RECOVERING AT HOME TONIGHT AFTER
SUFFERING A CONCUSSION FROM A
FALL WHEN SHE FAINTED.
SHE'S BEEN DEALING WITH A
STOMACH VIRUS ALL WEEK AND
BECAME DEHYDRATED.
HER SCHEDULED CONGRESSIONAL
TESTIMONY NEXT THURSDAY ABOUT
THE ATTACK ON THE U.S. CONSULATE
IN BENGHAZI HAS BEEN POSTPONED.
>>> SOME DEVELOPMENTS TO TELL
YOU ABOUT FROM HERE IN NEWTOWN.
FIRST, PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL BE
HERE TOMORROW.
THE WHITE HOUSE SAYS THE
PRESIDENT WILL MEET WITH THE
FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS, THE 20
CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS KILLED
IN THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
YESTERDAY.
AS FOR THE ALLEGED SHOOTER,
POLICE SAY THEY HAVE FOUND VERY
GOOD EVIDENCE IN HIS HOME AND
THEY ARE PIECING TOGETHER A
POSSIBLE MOTIVE.
THAT HOUSE US ALSO -- IS ALSO A
CRIME SCENE
LANZA'S MOTHER, THE SUSPECT'S
MOTHER, WAS KILLED IN THAT HOUSE
BEFORE THE DEADLY RAMPAGE AT THE
SCHOOL.
I WANT TO SHOW YOU THIS PICTURE
THAT WE GOT IN TO CNN JUST A
COUPLE OF HOURS AGO.
IT SHOWS THE SUSPECT IN 2005, HE
WAS ABOUT 13 YEARS OLD IN THIS
PICTURE.
HE WAS 20 YESTERDAY WHEN HE SHOT
HIMSELF DEAD AFTER THAT SHOOTING
RAMPAGE AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
CNN'S SUSAN CANDIOTTI IS ALSO
HERE IN NEWTOWN.
AND SHE HAS BEEN TRACKING THE
INVESTIGATION BOTH AT THE SCHOOL
AND AT THE SUSPECTED KILLER'S
HOME.
>> Reporter: INVESTIGATORS ARE
LEARNING MORE EACH DAY THAT MAY
EXPLAIN WHAT LED 20-YEAR-OLD
ADAM LANZA TO LAUNCH A VICIOUS
ATTACK ON YOUNG CHILDREN AND
ADULTS AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> OUR INVESTIGATORS AT THE
CRIME SCENE, THE SCHOOL AND
SECONDARILY AT THE SECONDARY
CRIME SCENE THAT WE DISCUSSED
WHERE THE FEMALE WAS LOCATED
DECEASED, DID PRODUCE SOME VERY
GOOD EVIDENCE IN THIS
INVESTIGATION THAT OUR
INVESTIGATORS WILL BE ABLE TO
USE IN HOPEFULLY PAINTING THE
COMPLETE PICTURE AS TO HOW AND
MORE IMPORTANTLY WHY THIS
OCCURRED.
>> Reporter: POLICE WON'T SAY
THAT WHAT EVIDENCE IS.
HOWEVER, INVESTIGATORS HAVE BEEN
CHECKING OUT GUN RANGES AND
SPORTING GOODS STORES.
THEY FOLLOWED A LEAD THE SHOOTER
TRIED TO BUY A GUN TUESDAY AT
THIS LOCATION.
AFTER SEARCHING STORE
SURVEILLANCE VIDEOS, THE TIP
DIDN'T PAN OUT.
>> TO DATE, ATF HAS NOT
UNCOVERED ANY INFORMATION THAT
WOULD SUBSTANTIATE THE FACT THAT
HE TRIED TO ACQUIRE GUNS
RECENTLY.
WE'RE ACTIVELY INVESTIGATING.
>> Reporter: FEDERAL GUN AGENTS
ALSO SAID THEY RECOVERED WEAPONS
AT THE HOME THE SHOOTER SHARED
FROM HIS MOTHER.
SOURCES SAY THREE MORE GUNS WERE
FOUND.
THESE THREE RIFLE MODELS, ALL
OLDER ARE BEING TRACED.
AT LEAST ONE HAS BEEN CONNECTED
TO THE MOTHER.
THREE MORE WEAPONS WERE
DISCOVERED WITH THE SHOOTER IN A
CLASSROOM WHERE HE TOOK HIS OWN
LIFE.
ACCORDING TO LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS, THE TWO HANDGUNS AND
SEMIAUTOMATIC LONG GUN CALLED A
BUSHMASTER WERE BOUGHT LEGALLY
BY HIS MOTHER.
THE CHIEF MEDICAL EXAMINER SAYS
THAT LONG GUN WAS USED TO KILL
SEVERAL VICTIMS.
>> I ONLY DID SEVEN OF THE
AUTOPSIES.
THE VICTIMS I HAD RANGED FROM
THREE TO 11 WOUNDS APIECE.
I ONLY SAW TWO OF THEM WITH
POSTRANGE SHOOTING.
ALL THE WOUNDS THAT I KNOW OF AT
THIS POINT WERE CAUSED BY THE
LONG WEAPON.
>> Reporter: ONE RELATIVE
DESCRIBES THE SHOOTER AS BEING A
VERY BRIGHT YOUNG MAN WHO AT
TIMES WAS HOMESCHOOLED BY HIS
MOTHER.
A LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIAL TELLS
US THAT HIS OLDER BROTHER SAYS
THAT HIS YOUNGER BROTHER WAS
AUTISTIC.
BUT SO FAR, NOTHING ADDS UP TO A
MOTIVE.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI, CNN, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER HAS
EMERGED AS ONE OF THE MORE
MYSTERIOUS FIGURES IN THE
INVESTIGATION.
HER SON APPARENTLY USED ONE OF
HER OWN GUNS TO KILL HER.
BUT THERE'S STILL SO MUCH WE
DON'T KNOW ABOUT HER.
CNN'S DAVID ARIOSTO JOINS US NOW
WITH WHAT'S NEW ON THIS.
DAVID, WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT
NANCY LANZA?
>> RIGHT HERE, WE'RE HERE IN
FRONT OF NANCY LANZA'S HOUSE.
IT'S A LITTLE BIT FURTHER DOWN
THE ROAD.
WE'VE BEEN DIGGING ON THAT VERY
QUESTION.
IT'S AN INCOMPLETE PICTURE AS TO
WHO THIS WOMAN REALLY WAS.
WE SPOKE WITH NEIGHBORS IN THE
AREA HERE.
MANY OF THEM HAVE RECALLED A
PERSON WHO IS A VERY PLEASANT
PERSON TO TALK WITH, LOVED
GARDENING, LOVED LANDSCAPING.
WOULD OFTEN ATTEND THESE SORT OF
DICE GAME, LADIES NIGHT
GET-TOGETHERS EVERY SO OFTEN,
PERHAPS EVERY COUPLE OF MONTHS.
SHE WAS THE KIND OF WOMAN THAT
SORT OF LEANED ON HER NEIGHBORS
BUT WAS ONLY REALLY FAMILIAR
WITH SOME OF THE NEIGHBORS IN
THE IMMEDIATE VICINITY.
YOU KIND OF THINK OF YOUR OWN
NEIGHBORHOOD AND HOW MANY
NEIGHBORS YOU ACTUALLY KNOW
OUTSIDE THOSE INITIAL FEW
BLOCKS.
SO THE NEIGHBORS THAT WE DID GET
TO SPEAK WITH DID GET TO KNOW
NANCY, BUT IT'S REALLY NOT ALL
THAT CLEAR WHAT WAS BEHIND THE
SCENES.
SHE MOVED HERE IN 1998 WITH HER
HUSBAND.
THEY HAD TWO BOYS.
SHE LATER DIVORCED AND RAISED
HER TWO BOYS IN THIS AREA.
WHAT TRANSPIRED LATER, HOWEVER,
IS REALLY SOMEWHAT UNCLEAR
BECAUSE THERE'S THIS OTHER SIDE
TO NANCY.
SHE HAD SEVERAL GUNS AND ONE
INDIVIDUAL THAT I SPOKE TO, A
BUSINESS OWNER, SAID THAT AT ONE
POINT SHE EVEN BRANDISHED A
RIFLE THAT SHE HAD RECENTLY
PURCHASED.
THIS INDIVIDUAL ALSO SAID THAT
SHE WOULD GO TARGET SHOOTING.
IT'S NOT CLEAR IF THAT OCCURRED
AT A RANGE OR JUST AROUND ON
CERTAIN TREES OR WHAT ACTUALLY
HE MEANT BY THAT.
BUT THEN LAW ENFORCEMENT AND ATF
AND FBI OFFICIALS SAID
ESSENTIALLY THAT WASN'T THE
CASE.
THEY WEREN'T AT A SHOOTING
RANGE.
THAT DIDN'T OCCUR.
BUT REALLY WHAT A LOT OF PEOPLE
HERE ARE TRYING TO GET ANSWERS
TO IS JUST WHAT MOTIVATED HER
SON TO DO THIS?
WHAT TRANSPIRED INSIDE THE
HOUSE -- AND THERE'S A LOT OF
PEOPLE REALLY REELING FROM THIS
AND LEFT WITH THIS SORT OF A
SPEECHLESS QUALITY ABOUT IT,
EVEN A DAY AFTER.
I KNOW MYSELF, I WENT DOWN TO
THE FIREHOUSE JUST YESTERDAY AS
FAMILIES WERE COMING OUT OF THIS
FIREHOUSE THAT WAS MEANT TO BE A
WEIGH STATION.
AND TOWARD THE EARLY MORNING
HOURS OF THAT TUMULTUOUS DAY,
YOU'D SEE FAMILIES WALKING OUT
WITH LOVED ONES, CHILDREN WHO
WERE TEARY-EYED, SHAKEN BUT
CLEARLY THEY WERE WALKING OUT
WITH THEIR CHILDREN.
AND AS THE DAY PROGRESSED, THESE
FAMILIES WOULD WALK OUT
CHILDLESS.
AND THIS IS JUST ONE OF THESE
THINGS THAT IT'S NOT GOING TO BE
AN EASY END EVEN AS THE DAYS --
>> AND DAVID, CLEARLY IT BREAKS
YOUR HEART.
AS YOU SAID, THERE ARE A LOT OF
UNANSWERED QUESTIONS.
THERE WERE SOME INITIAL REPORTS
THAT SHE, NANCY LANZA,
ORIGINALLY WORKED FOR THE
SCHOOL.
BUT THAT ISN'T TRUE, IS IT?
>> A LOT OF INFORMATION COMING
IN FROM ALL ANGLES HERE THAT WE
GET IN.
IT SEEMS CREDIBLE.
AND THEN IT TURNS OUT NOT TO BE
THE CASE.
THERE WERE SOME INITIAL LOCAL
REPORTS THAT INDICATED THAT SHE
MIGHT HAVE WORKED IN THE SCHOOL
SYSTEM.
WHAT WE LATER FOUND OUT IS THAT
SHE ACTUALLY HAD A BACKGROUND IN
FINANCE AND HAD TAKEN SOME TIME
OFF AND WAS STAYING HERE.
WHAT HER CONNECTION WAS TO THE
SCHOOL IS UNCLEAR.
IF THERE'S ANY, WHICH ALSO
RAISES MORE QUESTIONS AS TO WHY
HER SON CHOSE THIS SCHOOL TO GO
IN AND COMMIT THIS HEINOUS ACT.
>> DAVID ARIOSTO, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH FOR YOUR REPORTING.
WE KNOW THE SHOOTER HAD THREE
GUNS WITH HIM INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
THOSE GUNS WERE REGISTERED TO
HIS MOTHER.
BUT WE DON'T KNOW HOW HE GOT
THEM.
SO CAN ANYONE BE HELD
RESPONSIBLE FOR THIS DEADLY
ATTACK?
KAREN CONTI IS A TRIAL ATTORNEY
IN CHICAGO.
CAN WE EXPECT LAWSUITS TO BE
FILED AND AGAINST WHOM?
>> LAWSUITS GET FILED FOR A LOT
OF REASONS OTHER THAN MONEY
BECAUSE OBVIOUSLY MONEY DOESN'T
REPLACE CHILDREN.
A LOT OF PEOPLE FILE LAWSUITS TO
GET INFORMATION THAT THEY CAN'T
OTHERWISE GET THROUGH THE
AUTHORITIES.
SOMETIMES THEY JUST WANT TO
BLAME SOMEONE FOR AND HOLD
SOMEONE ACCOUNTABLE FOR THE
SENSELESS VIOLENCE.
AND SOMETIMES THEY JUST WANT TO
CHANGE THINGS IN THE FUTURE,
MAYBE CHANGE THE LAWS AND THE
SAFETY PROCEDURES.
SO JUST A NOTE ABOUT THAT, THE
PARENTS WHO ARE ANGRY AND UPSET
ABOUT THESE THINGS WILL BRING
LAWSUITS.
NOW, I JUST DON'T SEE A VIABLE
LAWSUIT HERE BECAUSE WHO ARE YOU
GOING TO SUE?
THE SCHOOL SEEMED LIKE THEY DID
A GREAT JOB, THEY HAD THE
PRECAUTIONS IN PLACE.
THIS WAS AN ADULT PERSON WHO DID
THIS.
YOU CAN'T HOLD THE PARENTS
RESPONSIBLE.
I DON'T REALLY SEE A VALID
LAWSUIT.
>> YEAH.
THAT WAS MY NEXT QUESTION
BECAUSE THE LEGAL DEFENSE HERE
WOULD BE THE FACT THAT THE
SUSPECT IS OVER THE AGE OF 18.
HE IS AN ADULT.
THEREFORE, HE'S THE ONLY ONE
RESPONSIBLE FOR THE ACTIONS.
BUT THEY WERE NOT HIS GUNS.
MAYBE HE SHOULDN'T HAVE GOTTEN
ACCESS TO THE GUNS.
BUT THE PERSON THE GUNS BELONGED
TO IS NOW DECEASED.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
AND THAT DOESN'T MEAN THAT THE
FAMILIES COULDN'T SUE THE ESTATE
OF THE MOTHER.
BUT THEY WOULD HAVE TO PROVE
THAT SHE IN SOME WAY, SHAPE OR
FORM KNEW THAT HE HAD THE
PROPENSITY TO DO THIS AND THIS
INDIVIDUAL HAD ASPERGER'S
SYNDROME, WHICH IS A FORM OF
AUTISM.
BUT IT HAS NO RELATION TO
VIOLENCE.
BUT IF SHE HAD PRIOR
KNOWLEDGE -- BUT EVEN THAT IS
VERY TENUOUS.
>> IN OREGON, WE SAW THE GUNS
BEING STOLEN.
WE SAW HERE THE GUNS BELONGED TO
THE MOTHER AND HE GOT ACCESS TO
THE GUNS.
CAN WE EXPECT TO SEE SOME
CHANGES IN THE LAW HERE BECAUSE
OF WHAT HAPPENED?
>> I THINK WHAT WE SAW IN
CONNECTICUT IS JUST PRIOR TO
THIS, AFTER THE AURORA,
COLORADO, THEATER SHOOTING, THEY
TRIED TO CHANGE THE LAWS AND
MAKE IT A LITTLE MORE STRINGENT.
BUT THERE WAS SUCH PROTEST THAT
IT ALL GOT STRICKEN DOWN.
I DO SEE, THOUGH, THAT WE HAVE A
LAW IN ILLINOIS CALLED THE
ILLINOIS SCHOOL SAFETY DRILL ACT
WHICH REQUIRES SCHOOLS TO
ANNUALLY HAVE DRILLS TO KIND OF
PREPARE FOR NOT ONLY THESE KINDS
OF THINGS BUT WEATHER ISSUES,
TORNADOES, FIRES AND THE LIKE,
EVACUATION PROCEDURES IN PLACE,
P.A. SYSTEMS, ET CETERA.
I THINK WE'RE GOING TO SEE A
MASSIVE AMOUNT OF LEGISLATION
ACROSS THE COUNTRY REQUIRING
SCHOOLS TO DO THIS.
>> KAREN CONTI, THANK YOU.
EARLIER ONE OF THE MOST
COMPELLING MOMENTS OF THIS
TRAGEDY, A FATHER WHO LOST HIS
DAUGHTER IN THE SHOOTING,
BRAVELY TELLS THE WORLD ABOUT
THE LITTLE GIRL THAT NOT ONLY HE
LOST BUT ONE OF THE MANY THAT WE
ALL LOST.
THAT'S NEXT.
DO YOU EVER WISH
WE HAD iPADS...
TO PRACTICE MATH
MORE?
I LOVE MATH!
BUT TWO iPADS
MEANS TWO DATA PLANS?
THAT'S CRAZY.
MAYBE NOT.
WITH AT&T MOBILE SHARE,
ADDING AN iPAD
IS JUST $10 A MONTH.
BUT HONESTLY, MOM AND DAD'S LOVE
IS ALL I REALLY NEED.
WE SHOULD KEEP THESE
FOR US.
WE SHOULD KEEP THESE.
WHAT?!
[ Male Announcer ]
AT&T MOBILE SHARE.
ADD AN iPAD
FOR JUST $10 A MONTH.
ONE PLAN. UP TO 10 DEVICES.
AT&T. RETHINK POSSIBLE.
>>> WE HAVE A QUICK UPDATE ON
TODAY'S DEVELOPMENTS IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
PRESIDENT BARACK OBAMA COMING
HERE TOMORROW TO MEET WITH THE
VICTIMS' FAMILIES.
HE'S ALSO EXPECTED TO ATTEND AN
INTERFAITH VIGIL SCHEDULED TO BE
HELD TOMORROW EVENING.
THE SHOOTER'S FATHER, PETER
LANZA, ISSUED A STATEMENT
TONIGHT OFFERING HIS CONDOLENCES
TO THE VICTIMS' FAMILIES.
AND WE HAVE LEARNED MORE ABOUT
THE VICTIMS INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
SIX WOMEN AND 20 STUDENTS DIED
THERE.
12 GIRLS, EIGHT BOYS, ALL 6 OR 7
YEARS OLD.
THE STATE'S CHIEF MEDICAL
EXAMINER SAYS ALL OF THEM DIED
FROM GUNSHOT WOUNDS.
THERE ARE SO MANY PEOPLE WHO ARE
NOW TRYING TO EMOTIONALLY HANDLE
THIS TRAGEDY, FRIENDS, FAMILY
AND RESIDENTS OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, TRYING TO START
DOWN THAT ROAD TO RECOVERY RIGHT
NOW.
OUR DR. SANJAY GUPTA VISITED A
GRIEF CENTER TODAY AND HE TALKED
TO SOME OF THEM.
LISTEN TO WHAT HE TOLD ANDERSON
EARLIER.
I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT TO EXPECT,
THIS WAS SO RAW, I DIDN'T KNOW
IF PEOPLE WERE GOING TO ACTUALLY
GO TO THIS CENTER
WE WEREN'T FILMING ANYTHING OUT
OF RESPECT FOR PEOPLE'S PRIVACY.
BUT PEOPLE WERE WALKING OUT WITH
CHILDREN, PROBABLY CHILDREN FROM
THE SCHOOL, A LOT OF PARENTS
WALKING WITH THEM INTO THE
SCHOOL.
AND THERE WERE PSYCHIATRISTS,
PSYCHOLOGISTS, CHILDREN'S
COUNSELORS IN THE SCHOOL.
I THINK WHAT WAS STRIKING IS
PEOPLE WERE GOING IN AND THEY
WERE STAYING IN FOR A LONG TIME.
THIS WAS SORT OF A GRIEVING BUT
ALSO HEALING GOING ON.
ALSO THIS WHOLE IDEA THAT THE
COMMUNITY WAS SORT OF AN
INDIVIDUAL, MEANING THAT YOU SAW
THAT SOMEONE ELSE WAS GOING
THROUGH THE SAME THING YOU WERE.
AND PEOPLE WERE BEING COMFORTED
BY THAT IN SOME WAY.
>> IT'S INTERESTING.
I WAS TALKING TO MY MOM WHO LOST
A SON, MY BROTHER.
AND SHE WAS SAYING FOR HER, IT
HELPED TO TALK ABOUT IT.
AND I'VE HEARD THAT FROM A LOT
OF PEOPLE HERE, THAT IT HELPS TO
TALK.
AND YET OTHER PEOPLE KIND OF
AREN'T READY TO TALK ABOUT IT OR
CAN'T TALK ABOUT IT AT THIS
POINT.
>> YEAH.
I THINK THE TIMING SEEMS TO BE
DIFFERENT FOR DIFFERENT PEOPLE
WHICH IS WHY I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT
TO EXPECT WHEN I WENT TO THAT
CRISIS CENTER TODAY.
BUT IT SEEMS LIKE THIS COMMUNITY
FOR THE MOST PART IS READY TO
TALK.
THIS IS OBVIOUSLY A SMALL SAMPLE
SIZE.
BUT PEOPLE ARE TALKING ABOUT IT.
AND THE FEELING OF ISOLATION,
THINKING THAT I'M GOING THROUGH
THIS ALONE, THAT NO ONE QUITE
UNDERSTANDS WHAT THIS HAS DONE
TO ME CAN BE QUITE PAINFUL AND
QUITE DAMAGING LONG TERM AS
WELL.
IF YOU SEE OTHER PEOPLE GOING
THROUGH IT -- EVEN JUST BEING
THERE IN THE CRISIS CENTER WITH
OTHER PEOPLE, I THINK, SEEMED TO
BE THERAPEUTIC FOR THEM.
>> AND A LOT OF PARENTS HERE AND
AROUND THE WORLD ARE TRYING TO
FIGURE OUT HOW TO TALK TO THEIR
KIDS ABOUT IT.
I TALKED TO SOME PARENTS LAST
NIGHT WHOSE KIDS WERE IN THE
SCHOOL AND THANKFULLY HAD
SURVIVED.
AND THEY WERE SAYING THEY WERE
WAITING FOR THEIR CHILD TO KIND
OF BRING IT UP TO THEM.
AND THAT'S ONE WAY TO DO IT.
>> YOU HAVE TO ASSUME THAT THEY
KNOW.
OBVIOUSLY THE CHILDREN IN THE
SCHOOL KNOW.
BUT EVEN OTHER CHILDREN IN THE
COMMUNITY KNOW, EVEN IF THEY
HAVEN'T BEEN WATCHING TELEVISION
JUST IN TODAY'S DAY AND AGE.
THE THING THAT KEEPS COMING BACK
IS THEY SORT OF DIRECT THE
CONVERSATION.
SO YOU SORT OF GET YOUR OWN
FEELINGS IN CHECK FIRST AS AN
ADULT OR AS A PARENT.
AND THEN YOU FILL IN DETAILS AS
APPROPRIATE, AS AGE APPROPRIATE,
LEAVING OUT OBVIOUSLY GRAPHIC
DETAILS.
BUT THIS WHOLE IDEA THAT YOU
DON'T WANT TO BE FALSE OR YOU
WANT TO BE VERY TRANSPARENT IN
TERMS OF WHAT YOU TELL THEM -- I
HAD THIS CONVERSATION WITH MY
DAUGHTER.
SHE STARTED ASKING ABOUT SOME OF
THE NAMES OF THE CHILDREN.
I THINK IT'S INTERESTING THEY
IMMEDIATELY WANT TO HUMANIZE
THIS IN SOME WAY FOR THEMSELVES.
IT'S A TOUGH CONVERSATION TO
HAVE.
SHE WANTED TO KNOW IF HER SCHOOL
WAS GOING TO BE SAFE.
I HAD TO SAY, LOOK, DADDY'S
SCHOOL NEVER HAD THIS HAPPEN TO
HIM.
MOMMY'S SCHOOL NEVER HAD IT
HAPPEN TO HER.
BUT THIS OBVIOUSLY HAPPENED.
WE DO THE BEST WE CAN TO KEEP
YOU SAFE.
IT'S TOUGH BUT AN IMPORTANT
CONVERSATION.
>> AND ONE FATHER REFUSES TO
THINK OF HIS DAUGHTER AS JUST
THE VICTIM OF A HORRIBLE CRIME.
THIS IS HOW ROBBIE PARKER SAYS
HE'LL REMEMBER HIS 6-YEAR-OLD
LITTLE GIRL.
>> I'D REALLY LIKE TO OFFER OUR
DEEPEST CONDOLENCES TO THE
FAMILIES WHO WERE DIRECTLY
AFFECTED BY THIS SHOOTING.
IT'S AN HORRIFIC TRAGEDY AND WE
WANT EVERYBODY TO KNOW THAT OUR
HEARTS AND OUR PRAYERS GO OUT TO
THEM.
THIS INCLUDES THE FAMILY OF THE
SHOOTER.
I CAN'T IMAGINE HOW HARD THIS
EXPERIENCE MUST BE FOR YOU AND I
WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT OUR FAMILY
AND OUR LOVE AND OUR SUPPORT
GOES OUT TO YOU AS WELL.
MY DAUGHTER, EMILIE, WOULD BE
ONE OF THE FIRST ONES TO BE
STANDING AND GIVING HER LOVE AND
SUPPORT TO ALL THOSE VICTIMS
BECAUSE THAT'S THE TYPE OF
PERSON THAT SHE IS, NOT BECAUSE
OF ANY PARENTING THAT MY WIFE
AND I COULD HAVE DONE, BUT
BECAUSE THOSE WERE THE GIFTS
THAT WERE GIVEN TO HER BY HER
HEAVENLY FATHER.
I HAVE TWO REALLY GOOD FRIENDS
AT HOME WHO HAVE SET UP A
FACEBOOK PAGE TO HELP RAISE
MONEY FOR EMILIE.
WHEN I'VE GOTTEN ON THAT AND
SEEN THE NUMBER OF PEOPLE WHO
HAVE COMMENTED AND EXPRESSED
THEIR CONDOLENCES, IT'S BEEN
QUITE OVERWHELMING.
AS THE DEEP PAIN BEGINS TO
SETTLE INTO OUR HEARTS, WE FIND
COMFORT REFLECTING ON THE
INCREDIBLE PERSON THAT EMILIE
WAS AND HOW MANY LIVES THAT SHE
WAS ABLE TO TOUCH IN HER SHORT
TIME HERE ON EARTH.
EMILIE WAS BRIGHT, CREATIVE AND
VERY LOVING.
EMILIE WAS ALWAYS WILLING TO TRY
NEW THINGS, OTHER THAN FOOD.
SHE LOVED TO USE HER TALENTS TO
TOUCH THE LIVES OF EVERYONE THAT
SHE CAME INTO CONTACT WITH.
SHE WAS AN EXCEPTIONAL ARTIST
AND SHE ALWAYS CARRIED AROUND
HER MARKERS AND PENCILS SO SHE
NEVER MISSED AN OPPORTUNITY TO
DRAW A PICTURE OR MAKE A CARD
FOR THOSE AROUND HER.
I CAN'T COUNT THE NUMBER OF
TIMES EMILIE NOTICED SOMEONE
FEELING SAD OR FRUSTRATED AND
WOULD RUSH TO FIND A PIECE OF
PAPER TO DRAW THEM A PICTURE OR
TO WRITE THEM AN ENCOURAGING
NOTE.
EMILIE'S CARD MAKING WAS
EXPRESSED BEAUTIFULLY THIS LAST
OCTOBER WHEN SHE PLACED A VERY
SPECIAL CARD SHE HAD MADE INTO
THE CASKET WITH HER GRANDPA, WHO
ALSO JUST RECENTLY DIED OF A
TRAGIC ACCIDENT.
EMILIE WAS A MENTOR TO HER TWO
LITTLE SISTERS AND DELIGHTED IN
TEACHING THEM HOW TO READ, DANCE
AND FIND THE SIMPLE JOYS IN
LIFE.
EMILIE'S LAUGHTER WAS INFECTIOUS
AND ALL THOSE WHO HAD THE
PLEASURE TO MEET HER WOULD AGREE
THAT THIS WORLD IS A BETTER
PLACE BECAUSE SHE'S BEEN IN IT.
SHE WAS THEIR BEST FRIEND.
THEY WERE ALL BORN WITHIN THREE
YEARS OF EACH OTHER SO BY LAW,
THEY'RE VERY CLOSE.
SHE WAS TEACHING MY MIDDLE
DAUGHTER TO READ.
SHE WOULD HELP MY YOUNGEST
DAUGHTER LEARN HOW TO MAKE
THINGS, SHOW HER HOW TO DO
CRAFTS.
THEY LOOKED UP TO HER AND THEY
LOOKED TO HER WHEN THEY NEEDED
COMFORT.
USUALLY THAT'S SAVED FOR A MOM
AND A DAD.
BUT IT WAS REALLY SWEET TO SEE
THE TIMES WHEN ONE OF THEM WOULD
FALL OR GET THEIR FEELINGS HURT,
HOW THEY WOULD RUN TO EMILIE TO
GET SUPPORT AND HUGS AND KISSES.
SHE WAS THE TYPE OF PERSON THAT
COULD JUST LIGHT UP A ROOM.
SHE ALWAYS HAD SOMETHING KIND TO
SAY ABOUT ANYBODY.
AND HER LOVE AND THE STRENGTH
THAT SHE GAVE US AND THE EXAMPLE
THAT SHE SHOWED TO US IS
REMARKABLE.
SHE IS AN INCREDIBLE PERSON.
AND I'M SO BLESSED TO BE HER
DAD.
I WAS LEAVING TO WORK AND SHE
WOKE UP BEFORE I LEFT.
AND I'VE ACTUALLY BEEN TEACHING
HER PORTUGUESE.
SO OUR LAST CONVERSATION WAS IN
PORTUGUESE.
AND SHE TOLD ME GOOD MORNING.
ASKED HOW I WAS DOING.
I SAID THAT I WAS DOING WELL.
SHE SAID THAT SHE LOVED ME.
I GAVE HER A KISS AND I WAS OUT
THE DOOR.
FREE AGENCY IS GIVEN TO ALL OF
US TO ACT AND DO WHAT WE WANT.
GOD CAN'T TAKE THAT AWAY FROM
US.
I KNOW THAT THAT'S SOMETHING
THAT HE WAS GIVEN AND THAT'S
WHAT HE CHOSE TO DO WITH IT.
I KNOW THAT GOD CAN'T TAKE THAT
AWAY.
I'M NOT MAD BECAUSE I HAVE MY
AGENCY TO MAKE SURE THAT I USE