AMERICA.
>> IT HAS GOT TO BE TACKLED, AND
ALL AREAS.
A PROPER DEBATE.
MY ARGUMENT IS, POLITICIANS HERE
DON'T WANT TO HAVE THIS DEBATE.
>> WELL, THEY HAVE TO.
THEY HAVE TO.
YOU HAVE TO HAVE A CONGRESSMAN
LIKE JERRY NADLER ON TODAY, YOU
HAVE TO HAVE A REPUBLICAN
CONGRESSMAN STEP UP, GET
TOGETHER.
THIS HAS TO BE TAKEN CARE OF, WE
CAN'T TALK ABOUT IT ANYMORE, WE
HAVE TO START DOING THINGS IN
AMERICA.
>> LISTEN, THANK YOU ALL FOR
JOINING ME.
ALL IN YOUR OWN WAY HAVE BEEN
THROUGH HORROR STORIES OF YOUR
OWN.
IT IS TIME.
PRESIDENT OBAMA TALKED IN A
MOVING AND EMOTIONAL WAY.
IT'S TIME FOR ACTION.
TIME THAT AMERICA'S POLITICIANS
JUST DID SOMETHING.
STOP WORRYING ABOUT THE GUN
LOBBY WHO MAKE MILLIONS,
BILLIONS OUT OF THIS TRADE IN
WHAT OFTEN LEADS TO APPALLING
DEATH IT IS TIME FOR SOME MORAL
.
>>> WELL, I'D LIKE TO SAY IT'S A
GOOD MORNING, BUT IT IS A VERY
SAD MORNING HERE IN NEWTOWN,
PENNSYLVANIA.
IT'S SATURDAY, DECEMBER 15th,
I'M ALI VELSHI AND YOU ARE
WATCHING CNN SPECIAL COVERAGE OF
THE CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTING
LIVE AS I SAY FROM PENNSYLVANIA.
IT IS ONE OF THE DEADLIEST
SHOOTING RAMPAGES IN U.S.
HISTORY.
ALL MORNING, WE'LL BRING YOU
UPDATES ON THE VICTIMS AND THE
INVESTIGATION.
WE NOW KNOW THE NAME OF THE
NEWTOWN SHOOTER.
WE'LL DIG IN ON WHAT WAS BEHIND
HIS MONSTROUS ACT AND A SECOND
CRIME SCENE TIED TO THE FIRST.
WHAT INVESTIGATORS FOUND WHEN
THEY WENT TO THE SUSPECTED
GUNMAN'S HOUSE.
>>> I'M HERE IN NEWTOWN,
PENNSYLVANIA.
BEHIND ME SOME DISTANCE IS THE
SCHOOL AT WHICH THIS TRAGIC
SHOOTING TOOK PLACE.
WE HAVE THIS STORY COVERED FROM
ALL ANGLES.
I WANT TO BRING IN MY COLLEAGUE
JOHN BERMAN IN NEWTOWN, IN THE
TOWN SQUARE.
JOHN, BRING US UP TO SPEED ON
WHAT WE'VE SEEN SINCE YESTERDAY
EVENING.
>> HEY, ALI, I'M STANDING IN
FRONT OF THE ST. ROSE OF LIMA
CHURCH WHERE LAST NIGHT THERE
WAS AN EMOTIONAL VIGIL WITH
ABOUT 1,000 PEOPLE HERE.
RESIDENTS POURED IN FOR THE 26
VICTIMS OF THIS TRAGIC ATTACK.
OF COURSE, 20 CHILDREN WERE
KILLED, SIX ADULTS, ALL AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AND WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT
THE SHOOTER, WHICH WE'RE GOING
TO GET INTO IN A MOMENT.
BUT FIRST, LET'S FOCUS RIGHT NOW
ON THE VICTIMS AND WHAT HAPPENED
AT THAT SCHOOL, AND HERE IN THIS
COMMUNITY.
THE COMMUNITY GATHERED TO SAY
THEIR PRAYERS AND GIVE THANKS
FOR THE SURVIVORS.
THEY ALSO SAID GOOD-BYE TO THE
VICTIMS.
ALL OF THEM TRYING TO COME TO
GRIPS WITH THIS HORRIBLE,
HORRIBLE TRAGEDY.
>> PEOPLE'S CHILDREN AND
BROTHERS AND SISTERS WERE TAKEN
FROM THEM.
PEOPLE'S SPOUSES, THOSE TEACHERS
AND ADMINISTRATORS WERE TAKEN
FROM US.
YET, WE STAND IN A CHURCH, AND
MANY OF US TODAY IN THE COMING
DAYS WILL RELY UPON THAT WHICH
WE HAVE BEEN TAUGHT AND THAT
WHICH WE INHERENTLY BELIEVE THAT
THERE IS FAITH FOR A REASON.
AND THAT FAITH ITSELF IS GOD'S
GIFT.
IN THESE TIMES OF TROUBLES WHEN
THE UNTHINKABLE HAPPENS IN OUR
VERY MIDST, OUR FAITH IS TESTED.
NOT JUST IN THE RELIGIOUS SENSE,
NOT JUST NECESSARILY OUR FAITH
IN GOD, BUT OUR FAITH IN
COMMUNITY, AND WHO WE ARE AND
WHAT WE COLLECTIVELY ARE.
>> Reporter: OFFICIALS HERE IN
NEWTOWN ARE EXPECTED TO BEGIN
RELEASING THE NAMES OF THE
VICTIMS ABOUT TWO HOURS FROM
NOW.
THERE'S THAT NEWS CONFERENCE
SCHEDULED FOR 8:00 A.M. EASTERN
TIME.
THEN WE WILL HAVE THE NAMES,
REALLY, TO PUT IN OUR PRAYERS.
WE WANT TO THINK, THOUGH, FOR A
MOMENT ABOUT THE PARENTS OF THE
VICTIMS AND WHAT THEY'RE GOING
THROUGH THIS MORNING.
IT IS ALMOST UNIMAGINABLE.
THE BODIES OF THOSE CHILDREN
REMAIN INSIDE THE SCHOOL THIS
MORNING STILL IN PLACE WHERE
THEY WERE SHOT.
POLICE SAY, OF COURSE, IT'S
STILL AN ACTIVE CRIME SCENE, SO
THE BODIES OF THE CHILDREN, THE
ADULTS, AND THE SHOOTER, THEY'RE
NOT BEING MOVED AT ALL RIGHT
NOW.
WE P WANT TO GO BACK FOR A FEW
MINUTES TO SEE HOW THIS TRAGEDY
UNFOLDED.
TO PIECE TOGETHER HOW IT WENT
DOWN.
HERE'S A SMALL PART OF THE RADIO
TRANSMISSIONS BETWEEN THE POLICE
AS THEY GOT WORD OF THIS
SHOOTING.
>> CALLER IS INDICATING SHE
THINKS SOMEONE'S SHOOTING IN THE
BUILDING.
THE FRONT GLASS HAS BEEN BROKEN
OUT, THEY'RE UNSURE WHY.
ALL UNITS, THE INDIVIDUAL I HAVE
ON THE PHONE IS CONTINUING TO
HEAR WHAT HE BELIEVES TO BE
GUNFIRE.
UNITS RESPONDING TO SANDY HOOK
AT THIS TIME, THE SHOOTING
APPEARS TO HAVE SHOT -- THE
SCHOOL IS IN LOCKDOWN.
>> Reporter: WHAT THEY FOUND AT
THE SCHOOL WAS A HORRIFYING
SCENE.
THERE HAVE BEEN GRIEF COUNSELORS
ON-SITE, NOT JUST FOR THE
FAMILIES, BUT ALSO TO SPEAK TO
THE FIRST RESPONDERS WHO SAY
IT'S SOME OF THE WORST VISIONS,
WORST SIGHTS THEY'VE SEEN IN
THEIR LONG, LONG CAREERS.
ANDERSON COOPER RIGHT NOW TAKES
US THROUGH THIS TRAGEDY.
>> ALL UNITS, THE INDIVIDUAL I
HAVE ON THE PHONE IS CONTINUING
TO HEAR WHAT HE BELIEVES TO BE
GUNFIRE.
>> Reporter: THE FIRST WORD WAS
CHILLING, IT ONLY GOT WORSE.
>> THEY'RE REPORTING MULTIPLE
FATALITIES INVOLVED IN THIS
SHOOTING AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
>> Reporter: WITH EACH NEW
REPORT, THE HORROR DEEPENED.
>> REPORTS SAY THE NUMBER OF
DEAD CLOSER TO 30 THAN TO 20 AND
SADLY MOST OF THEM ARE CHILDREN.
>> Reporter: EVERY DETAIL, EVERY
FACT BROUGHT MORE SADNESS.
EACH FRESH PIECE OF INFORMATION,
A PART OF THE PICTURE, A SCHOOL,
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADE, A SANCTUARY THAT WAS
SUPPOSED TO BE A PLACE OF SAFETY
TORN APART.
>> SHE HEARD THE INTERCOM CAME
ON TO THE SCHOOL AND SHE HEARD A
SCREAM AND A GUN SHOT, TWO GUN
SHOTS.
AND THEN THE SCHOOL WENT INTO
LOCKDOWN.
>> A STUDENT'S TEENAGE BIG
BROTHER DESCRIBING THE SOUNDS OF
A GUNMAN ON THE LOOSE AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY.
>> OFFDUTY TROOPERS RESPONDED TO
THE SCHOOL AND POLICE UPON
ARRIVAL ENTERED THE SCHOOL AND
BEGAN A COMPLETE ACTIVE SHOOTER
SEARCH OF THE BUILDING.
>> THEY ARRIVED TO CARNAGE.
THE KILLER SAYS A LAW
ENFORCEMENT SOURCE WITH DETAILED
KNOWLEDGE WAS DRESSED FOR BATTLE
IN BLACK FATIGUES AND ARMED FOR
MASS MURDER WITH TWO PISTOLS AND
A MILITARY-STYLE RIFLE.
STUDENTS WERE TOLD TO HIDE IN
CORNERS, TEACHERS RISKED THEIR
OWN LIVES TO PULL BOYS AND GIRLS
TO SAFETY.
>> I'M SO GRATEFUL TO THE
TEACHER WHO SAVED THEM.
>> YOU THINK THE TEACHER SAVED
HIS LIFE?
>> HE DID.
HE HAD BULLETS GOING BY HIM AND
SHE GRABBED HIM AND ANOTHER
CHILD AND PULLED HIM INTO A
CLASSROOM.
>> Reporter: EVENTUALLY THE KIDS
WERE EVACUATED TO A NEARBY FIRE
HOUSE WHERE FRANTIC PARENTS
DESCENDED.
>> IT WAS TERRIFYING.
I'M STILL TERRIFIED.
I STILL DON'T KNOW WHAT
HAPPENED.
I KNOW THERE ARE SOME PEOPLE
MISSING THAT HAVE BEEN TAKEN TO
THE HOSPITAL.
>> HIS SON WAS OKAY, HIS SON'S
TEACHER WAS ALIVE, AS WELL.
20 OTHER CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS
WERE KILLED.
THE DEAD BELIEVE TO INCLUDE
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST
AND THE PRINCIPAL.
POLICE DISCOVERED ANOTHER ADULT
VICTIM, THE GUNMAN'S MOTHER
REPORTEDLY AT HOME IN NEWTOWN.
THE GUNMAN TOO IS DEAD.
POLICE SAY THEY FIRED NO SHOTS.
A TIGHT KNIT COMMUNITY,
INCLUDING A NURSE WHO LIVED
NEARBY AND RUSHED TO HELP
DISTRAUGHT.
>> I SEE YOU'VE BEEN CRYING.
>> YES.
>> IS IT BECAUSE WHAT YOU SAW?
>> ONE OF THE COPS -- THE WORST
THING HE'D EVER SEEN IN HIS
ENTIRE CAREER, BUT IT WAS WHEN
THEY TOLD THE PARENTS.
ALL OF THESE PARENTS WERE
WAITING FOR THEIR CHILDREN TO
COME OUT.
THEY THOUGHT THEY WERE, YOU
KNOW, STILL ALIVE.
THERE'S 20 PARENTS THAT WERE
JUST TOLD THAT THEIR CHILDREN
ARE DEAD.
IT WAS AWFUL.
>> Reporter: AWFUL.
AND LATE TODAY SPEAKING FOR THE
NATION BUT ALSO AS A FATHER, AN
EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT OBAMA FOUGHT
BACK TEARS.
>> THIS EVENING, MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT EVERY PARENT IN
AMERICA WILL DO, WHICH IS HUG
OUR CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER.
AND WE'LL TELL THEM THAT WE LOVE
THEM.
AND WE'LL REMIND EACH OTHER HOW
DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT.
AND THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT
NOW.
>> Reporter: YOU SAW IT IN THE
PRESIDENT'S FACE, YOU HEARD IT
IN HIS VOICE.
I SIMPLY CAN'T THINK OF AN EVENT
IN RECENT MEMORY THAT TOUCHED SO
MANY PEOPLE, SEEMED TO AFFECT
THEM SO DIRECTLY RIGHT IN THEIR
HEARTS, RIGHT IN THEIR SOULS.
FOR MORE INFORMATION ABOUT HOW
YOU CAN HELP THOSE PEOPLE
DIRECTLY AFFECTED HERE BY THE
SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN, GO TO
CNN.COM/IMPACTALL.
I WANT TO GO BACK TO ALI VELSHI
JUST DOWN THE STREET HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
ALI?
>> YOU KNOW, JOHN, YOU SEE THOSE
PARENTS SO EMOTIONALLY
DISTRAUGHT AND SO MUCH OF THE
COMMUNITY LIKE THAT AND
ELSEWHERE IN THE COMMUNITY,
THERE'S THIS FEELING ABOUT HOW
STUNNED EVERYBODY IS.
WHEN YOU TRAVEL AROUND THIS TOWN
AS I DID LAST NIGHT, JOHN, AS
YOU SAW, IT'S A BIT OF A SLEEPY
PLACE, IT'S A QUIET PLACE.
IN THE LAST TEN YEARS, I
UNDERSTAND THERE'S BEEN ONE
HOMICIDE HERE.
WE ARE NOW LEARNING A LITTLE BIT
MORE ABOUT THE MAN WHO POLICE
SAY WAS THE SHOOTER.
HE IS 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA.
LAST NIGHT, OUR PIERS MORGAN GOT
INSIGHT ON LANZA FROM A FORMER
CLASSMATE.
>> HE WAS REALLY QUIET, HE KEPT
TO HIMSELF.
HE WAS A LITTLE FIDGETY, A
LITTLE UNEASY SOMETIMES IF YOU
WERE TO LOOK AT HIM.
I THINK HE WAS JUST SOCIALLY NOT
REALLY INTO GOING OUT THERE AND
MAKING AS MANY FRIENDS AS
EVERYONE ELSE WAS DOING IN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND MIDDLE
SCHOOL.
PREFERRED TO STAY TO HIMSELF.
>> Reporter: ADAM LANZA'S BODY
WAS FOUND IN THE SCHOOL.
HIS MOTHER'S BODY WAS FOUND AT
THE HOME THEY SHARED ABOUT 2 1/2
MILES FROM HERE.
THAT IS WHERE OUR MARY SNOW IS
STANDING BY THIS MORNING.
MARY, THE AREA THAT YOU ARE IN,
BIG HOUSES, IT'S A PROSPEROUS
AREA, A QUIET AREA.
THERE AREN'T EVEN STREET LIGHTS
AROUND YOU.
THE ONLY LIGHTS YOU'VE GOT ARE
THE ONES PROVIDED BY OUR LIGHTS.
THIS IS NOT SOMETHING THAT
AREA'S USED TO.
WHAT DO WE KNOW NOW ABOUT THE
AREA AND ADAM LANZA?
>> YEAH, ALI, WE -- IT'S
BELIEVED HE DID LIVE WITH HIS
MOTHER AND THAT HOUSE IS BEHIND
ME ON THIS QUIET ROAD WHICH IS
NOW CLOSED OFF BY POLICE, AND,
OF COURSE, AS YOU SAID, PEOPLE
ARE ABSOLUTELY STUNNED BY THIS.
IN TERMS OF WHAT WE KNOW ABOUT
HIM, DISTURBED IS ONE WORD A
NEIGHBOR USED TO DESCRIBE HIM.
OTHERS DESCRIBED HIM AS
DIFFERENT, SOCIALLY AWKWARD, AND
QUIET.
BUT ONE WOMAN WHO CAME BY
YESTERDAY, SHE'S A FORMER SCHOOL
BUS DRIVER AND HE WAS ON HER
ROUTE, SHE SAID, YOU KNOW, HE
WAS A QUIET KID BUT SHE NEVER
SAW ANYTHING DANGEROUS, YOU
KNOW, ABOUT HIM.
AND A NUMBER OF PEOPLE WE TALKED
TO IN THIS AREA, EVEN THOUGH IT
IS A VERY CLOSED TIGHT-KNIT
COMMUNITY, IT'S PHYSICALLY VERY
LARGE.
AND HOUSES ARE PRETTY SEPARATE
FROM EACH OTHER AT A GOOD
DISTANCE.
AND MANY PEOPLE REALLY WERE NOT
FAMILIAR WITH THE FAMILY.
BUT IT'S REALLY KIND OF A MIXED
PICTURE.
BUT ONE WORD WE DID HERE OFTEN
WAS VERY QUIET AND DIFFERENT.
>> MARY, LET'S UNDERSTAND ABOUT
THE HANDGUNS.
THERE WERE TWO HANDGUNS USED IN
THE ATTACK.
A SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPON FOUND IN
A CAR NEARBY.
WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT HOW HE GOT
HIS HANDS ON THOSE GUNS?
>> Reporter: WELL, OUR OWN SUSAN
CANDIOTTI HAS BEEN REPORTING
THAT THOSE HANDGUNS WERE LEGALLY
PURCHASED AND THEY WERE
PURCHASED AND REGISTERED TO
LANZA'S MOTHER NANCY, AND THAT'S
WHAT WE KNOW ABOUT THOSE GUNS.
>> IT'S A STRICT GUN LAWS IN
CONNECTICUT.
THEY HAVE TO BE REGISTERED.
THEY'VE GOT A GUN REGISTRY IN
THE STATE, WHICH IS WHY THE
AUTHORITIES, I THINK, WERE ABLE
TO TRACE THAT BACK SO QUICKLY TO
BEING GUNS SOLD TO HIS MOTHER.
THANK YOU.
MARY SNOW IS OUTSIDE THE
LOCATION WHERE NANCY LANZA LIVED
WITH HER SON ADAM LANZA.
OVER THE NEXT DAYS AND WEEKS
WE'RE GOING TO HEAR A LOT ABOUT
THE GUNMAN AND THEORYS AND
EXPLANATIONS ABOUT HOW SOMETHING
THIS HORRIBLE COULD'VE HAPPENED.
UNTIL THEN, NOW IS THE TIME TO
REMEMBER THE VICTIMS AND THE
SURVIVORS OF THE DAY THAT STOLE
THE INNOCENCE FROM HUNDREDS AND
HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE.
>> THIS IS A VERY, VERY TRAGIC,
TRAGIC SCENE FOR EVERYBODY.
CERTAINLY OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN
FOR THE FAMILIES HERE.
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, ABOUT 9:30,
9:40, WE HEARD NOISES, AND THE
ANNOUNCEMENT SYSTEM WAS STILL  N
ON, SO IT DIDN'T GO OFF SO YOU
COULD HEAR WHAT SOUNDED LIKE
POPS, GUN SHOTS.
>> HER TEACHER MANAGED TO TAKE
TWO CHILDREN OUT OF THE HALLWAY,
PULL THEM IN THE CLASSROOM, LOCK
THE DOOR, AND MOVE EVERYBODY
OVER TO THE OTHER SIDE OF THE
ROOM.
>> WE JUST TOLD A LITTLE BOY
ABOUT HIS SISTER NOW.
AND WHO AM I GOING TO PLAY WITH,
HE SAID?
I HAVE NOBODY TO PLAY WITH NOW.
EXCUSE ME.
>> WHEN YOUR FIRST GRADER GOES
TO BED AND SAYS, MOMMY, IS
ANYONE FROM MY CLASS LAST YEAR,
ARE THEY ALL OKAY?
AND YOU LOOK AT THEM AND SAY I'M
NOT REALLY SURE.
>> YOU CAN NEVER BE PREPARED FOR
THIS KIND OF INCIDENT.
WHAT HAS HAPPENED, WHAT HAS
TRANSPIRED AT THAT SCHOOL
BUILDING WILL LEAVE A MARK ON
THIS COMMUNITY AND EVERY FAMILY
IMPACTED.
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Sharable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>>> MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF
THE VICTIMS.
AND IN THE WORDS SCRIPTURE, HEAL
THE BROKEN HEARTED AND BIND UP
THEIR WOUNDS.
>> Reporter: BIND UP THEIR
WOUNDS.
WELCOME BACK TO NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, EVERYONE.
GOOD MORNING.
WE WOULD LIKE TO WELCOME OUR
VIEWERS IN THE UNITED STATES AND
AROUND THE WORLD.
YOU'RE WATCHING CNN'S SPECIAL
COVERAGE OF THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
I'M JOHN BERMAN STANDING IN
FRONT OF THE ST. ROSE OF LIMA
CATHOLIC CHURCH WHERE LAST NIGHT
THERE WAS A LARGE CEREMONY TO
MOURN THE VICTIMS LOST.
WE'RE AWAITING A NEWS CONFERENCE
HERE AT 8:00 A.M. EASTERN TIME
IN CONNECTICUT WHERE AUTHORITIES
ARE EXPECTED TO RELEASE THE
NAMES OF THE CHILDREN AND ADULTS
KILLED AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
26 PEOPLE KILLED THERE, 20
CHILDREN, 6 ADULTS, THE MOTHER
OF THE VICTIM ALSO FOUND DEAD AT
A SEPARATE LOCATION.
I WANT TO CHECK IN NOW WITH NICK
VALENCIA IN THE CNN NEWSROOM.
ONE OF THEM, THE SCHOOL
PRINCIPAL.
NICK, WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT HER?
>> GOOD MORNING, JOHN.
AS YOU MENTIONED, I'M HERE AT
THE CNN CENTER IN ATLANTA WHERE
WE'RE WORKING ON GATHERING THE
LATEST INFORMATION ON THE
VICTIMS OF THIS HORRIBLE
TRAGEDY, THE CONNECTICUT SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
AS YOU MENTIONED, 47-YEAR-OLD
PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG,
DESCRIBED AS THE KIND OF PERSON
YOU WOULD WANT EDUCATING YOUR
KIDS, JOHN.
SHE WAS A VERY INVOLVED EDUCATOR
WITH MEMORABLE ENTHUSIASM
ACCORDING TO THOSE THAT KNEW
HER.
SHE SPENT HER ENTIRE CAREER
RISING THROUGH THE RANKS OF THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SYSTEM,
TEACHING IN SMALL COMMUNITIES
WHERE SHE WAS A FIXTURE IN
SCHOOLS BEFORE COMING TO SANDY
HOOK.
SHE TAUGHT IN LOCAL ELEMENTARY
SCHOOLS, MIDDLE SCHOOLS, AND
HIGH SCHOOLS.
THOSE WHO REMEMBER HER SAY SHE
CREATED AN ENVIRONMENT, JOHN,
THAT MADE PEOPLE FEEL ACCEPTED
AND IMPORTANT.
NOT ONLY WAS SHE AN EDUCATOR,
JOHN, SHE WAS ALSO A MOTHER AND
LEAVES BEHIND TWO DAUGHTERS AND
THREE STEPDAUGHTERS, AND AS WE
MENTIONED, SHE WAS JUST 47 YEARS
OLD.
JOHN?
>> WE HEARD SO MANY OF THE
PARENTS IN THIS COMMUNITY, SO
MANY OF THE SURVIVING CHILDREN
TALK ABOUT WHAT AN AMAZING
LEADER SHE WAS INSIDE THIS
SCHOOL COMMUNITY.
AND ONE OF THE MOST INTERESTING
THINGS, SHE'D BEEN DEALING WITH
THE ISSUE OF SCHOOL SECURITY
LATELY, TAKING SOME NEW MEASURES
AT THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
WHAT WERE THEY?
>> EARLIER THIS YEAR, JOHN, SHE
OVERSAW THE INSTALLATION OF A
NEW SECURITY PROJECT THERE AT
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
THEY TOOK SECURITY VERY
SERIOUSLY THERE, AND THIS NEW
PROGRAM THEY INSTALLED, IT MADE
VISITORS THAT SHOWED UP AT THE
FRONT ENTRANCE HAVE TO RING THE
BELL, RING THE BUZZER IN ORDER
TO GET IN THE SCHOOL.
THE SCHOOL DOORS LOCKED AT ABOUT
9:30 IN THE MORNING.
WE'RE STILL TRYING TO PIECE
TOGETHER THE DETAILS OF HOW THIS
SUSPECTED SHOOTER GOT INTO SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THOSE DETAILS ARE STILL VERY
VAGUE.
BUT AS YOU MENTIONED, JOHN, IN
JUST A COUPLE OF HOURS AT ABOUT
8:00 A.M. EASTERN, LOCAL
AUTHORITIES WILL BE HOLDING A
PRESS CONFERENCE TO GIVE US MORE
INFORMATION ON THE VICTIMS.
THE STORY REALLY IS ABOUT THE
VICTIMS OF THIS SENSELESS
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT.
WE'LL BRING YOU MORE DETAILS
ABOUT THE VICTIMS AND HOPEFULLY
MORE INFORMATION AS IT UNFOLDS
THERE OUT OF CONNECTICUT IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
JOHN?
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH, NICK
VALENCIA.
AS YOU SAID, IT IS ABOUT THE
VICTIMS.
26 PEOPLE KILLED IN ALL AT THE
SCHOOL, 20 KIDS AGES 5 TO 10,
SIX GROWN-UPS, SO MANY FUTURES
AHEAD OF THEM THAT WILL NEVER BE
REALIZED.
I WANT TO GO NOW BACK TO ALI
VELSHI NEAR THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
HEY, ALI.
>> Reporter: JOHN, YOU KNOW, AS
I SAID WE ARE AT A FIELD, A
FOOTBALL FIELD, WHICH
AUTHORITIES SET UP AROUND HERE
SO THAT THE MEDIA COULD GATHER.
OBVIOUSLY THERE'S MEDIA HERE
FROM ALL OVER THE NORTHEAST, ALL
OVER THE UNITED STATES, AND, IN
FACT, FROM OTHER COUNTRIES.
LAST NIGHT I SAW SOME PEOPLE
HERE FROM A RUSSIAN TELEVISION
STATION.
WE'VE GOT SOME CANADIANS NEAR
US.
THE SCHOOL IS -- THIS IS A TIGHT
LITTLE TOWN, JOHN.
AS YOU KNOW, IT DOESN'T HAVE
SPACE FOR EVERYBODY CONVERGING
ON IT.
THE SCHOOL IS BEHIND US SOME
DISTANCE WHERE ADAM LANZA LIVED
WAS ABOUT 2 1/2 MILES AWAY.
AND THIS IS A LITTLE TOWN THAT
COULD NOT HAVE IMAGINED THE
HORROR THAT UNFOLDED AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WHAT CAN YOU DO TO KEEP YOUR
CHILDREN SAFE IF YOU'RE EVER,
EVER IN THIS KIND OF SITUATION?
CNN'S BRIAN TODD TALKED TO A
SCHOOL SECURITY CHIEF.
>> Reporter: A NIGHTMARE
SCENARIO FOR ANY SCHOOL SECURITY
OFFICIAL, BUT MICHAEL BLOW HAS
SOME IDEAS ON HOW TO AVOID MASS
CASUALTIES IF A GUNMAN'S INSIDE
YOUR SCHOOL.
>> HOW DO YOU RESPOND IF THERE
ARE KIDS ALL AROUND?
>> WELL, I THINK THAT'S WHERE
THE TRAINING COMES IN.
>> Reporter: HE'S HEAD OF
SECURITY FOR PRINCE GEORGES
COUNTY PUBLIC SCHOOLS IN
MARYLAND.
A FORMER DEPUTY POLICE CHIEF WHO
ONCE HAD TO LOCK DOWN A SCHOOL.
HE TOOK US THROUGH AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL THAT OFFICIALS DIDN'T
WANT US TO NAME.
SHOWED US WHAT TO DO IF THAT
NIGHTMARE UNFOLDS.
>> EXITS ARE OBVIOUSLY KEY,
RIGHT?
>> YES.
>> FIND THE NEAREST ONE.
>> ABSOLUTELY, ABSOLUTELY.
AND IT'S IMPORTANT TO BE
FAMILIAR WITH THE BUILDING.
THAT'S WHY, AGAIN, WE ENCOURAGE
JUST LITTLE THINGS.
A BUILDING FAMILIARIZATION, JUST
WALKING THE OUTSIDE OF THE
BUILDING SO YOU KNOW IF YOU
BELIEVE THIS PARTICULAR DOOR IF
IT COMES TO A CREEK OR A PARKING
LOT OR A BUSY INTERSECTION.
>> Reporter: ADULTS AND
STUDENTS, HE SAYS, HAVE TO HAVE
THAT EXIT AWARENESS.
BUT IF YOU'RE STUCK INSIDE,
MICHAEL BLOW SAYS WHILE
BATHROOMS MAY BE A TEMPTING
PLACE TO HIDE AT FIRST, NOT A
GOOD IDEA.
AS YOU CAN SEE, A VERY CONFINED
SPACE AND USUALLY NO WAY OUT.
COURTYARDS, HE SAYS, ARE EQUALLY
TEMPTING BUT ALSO NOT THE BEST
PLACES BECAUSE THEY'RE OFTEN
ENCLOSED.
>> MICHAEL, IF THERE'S A
CLASSROOM, THERE'S A GUNMAN OUT
THERE, WE'VE HEARD SHOTS, DON'T
KNOW WHERE HE IS.
WHAT DO WE DO?
WE LOCK, TURN LIGHTS OFF, CLOSE
WINDOWS?
>> WELL, CERTAINLY THERE ARE A
HOST OF THINGS WE WOULD DO IN AN
EMERGENCY THAT WOULD INCLUDE
LOCKING DOORS TO MAKE SURE THAT
WE ARE ABLE TO FORTIFY THAT
ENTRANCE WAY AS BEST AS WE CAN.
AGAIN, IF THERE ARE NO SAFE
ALTERNATIVES FOR EVACUATING THE
BUILDING AND THAT WAY IF SOMEONE
WAS TO WALK BY THE ROOM THAT
THEY WOULDN'T HAVE AN EASY SIGHT
PICTURE OF ANYONE IN THE ROOM.
>> ADULTS IN THE ROOM, HE SAYS,
SHOULD TALK THE KIDS THROUGH IT
AS CALMLY AS POSSIBLE.
>> WHAT ABOUT LARGE ROOMS LIKE
GYMS?
>> AGAIN --
>> WOULD YOU GO IN, AVOID IT?
>> WELL, AGAIN, THERE'S NOT A
LOT OF PLACES TO CONCEAL
YOURSELVES AS YOU SEE THERE, BUT
THERE'S A WAY TO GET TO THE
OTHER SIDE OF THE BUILDING.
>> BLOW DIDN'T WANT TO GIVE AWAY
TOO MANY PREEMPTIVE SCHOOL
MEASURES, BUT SAYS THEY
SOMETIMES USE WANDING DEVICES TO
SCREEN STUDENTS.
BUT HE SAYS SOME OF THE BEST
SCREENING IS AWARENESS OF WHO'S
TROUBLED, WHO'S BEING BULLIED,
HAVING THAT RADAR UP FOR
POTENTIAL ASSAILANTS.
>> OF COURSE, WE KNOW THAT
DESPITE ANY SCHOOL'S BEST
EFFORTS, IF SOMEONE IS
DETERMINED TO CAUSE HARM, THEY
WILL FIND A WAY AND SADLY THAT'S
EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
JOHN, A COUPLE OF INTERESTING
THINGS.
DAVID WAS HERE YESTERDAY
AFTERNOON AND WENT TO THE FIRE
HOUSE, IT WAS A RENDEZVOUS POINT
TO MEET UP WITH THEIR KIDS.
AND HE SAW THEM GOING IN AND IN
MANY CASES PARENTS CAME OUT WITH
THEIR KIDS AND HE SAID THE
REACTION ON THEIR FACES WAS OF
SUCH RELIEF BUT STRAIN AND
STRESS AND THEN THERE WERE THOSE
PARENTS WHO WENT THERE EXPECTING
TO FIND THEIR KIDS AND LEFT
WITHOUT THEM.
THEY STILL HAVEN'T SEEN THEIR
KIDS.
THE BODIES WERE STILL BEING
PROCESSED LAST NIGHT.
POLICE WANTED TO GET TENTATIVE
IDENTIFICATIONS ON ALL OF THE
BODIES BEFORE THEY WERE ABLE TO
RELEASE THAT INFORMATION TO
THEIR PARENTS.
AND OF COURSE, WE WILL HEAR
ABOUT THAT THIS MORNING PROBABLY
WITHIN THE NEXT COUPLE OF HOURS.
POLICE ARE EXPECTING TO UPDATE
US AT ABOUT 8:00 EASTERN TIME.
JOHN, THE OTHER THING LET'S TALK
ABOUT.
YOU WERE IN HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY,
LAST NIGHT, WHICH FOR A WHILE
WAS TREATED AS THE SCENE OF A
CRIME.
TELL US WHAT WAS GOING ON IN
HOBOKEN.
>> Reporter: YOU KNOW, ALI, IT
WAS SO INTERESTING, FOR MUCH OF
YESTERDAY, HOBOKEN, THE STREET
WAS ABUZZ WITH ACTIVITY.
HOBOKEN CITY POLICE, JERSEY CITY
POLICE, BOMB SQUAD
REPRESENTATIVES AND THE FBI.
THE REASON WAS THEY WERE GOING
INTO THE APARTMENT OF RYAN LANZA
WHO IS THE BROTHER OF THE
SHOOTER, THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER
ADAM LANZA.
APPARENTLY ADAM HAD HIS
BROTHER'S I.D. ON HIM WHEN HE
WENT INTO THE SCHOOL AND
CONDUCTED THE SHOOTING.
SO AUTHORITIES WENT RIGHT TO
RYAN'S APARTMENT IN HOBOKEN,
TOOK HIM INTO CUSTODY BRIEFLY
FOR QUESTIONING ALSO QUESTIONED
SOME FRIENDS WHO MAY HAVE LIVED
WITH HIM THERE.
IT WAS JUST A CONFUSING
SITUATION.
THEY REMOVED SOME MATERIALS FROM
THAT APARTMENT TRYING TO PIECE
TOGETHER EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED.
AS THE NIGHT WORE ON, THE POLICE
PRESENCE BECAME LESS AND LESS, I
THINK AS THEY GATHERED MORE
INFORMATION AND REALIZED THAT
MAY NOT HAVE BEEN THE CENTER OF
THEIR INTERESTS, SHALL WE SAY
GOING FORWARD.
I'M STANDING IN FRONT OF ALI,
ALSO I SHOULD MENTION THE ST.
ROSE CHURCH OF LIMA WHERE LAST
NIGHT THERE WAS THAT CANDLE
LIGHT VIGIL.
YOU WALK INSIDE THE CHURCH HERE
AND THERE ARE TWO POSTER BOARDS
WHERE PEOPLE HAVE ALREADY POSTED
DOZENS AND DOZENS OF NOTES OF
GRIEF AND SOLIDARITY WITH THE
PEOPLE IN THIS COMMUNITY.
MANY PEOPLE HAVE COME FROM OUT
OF TOWN TO POST NOTES THERE.
AND WE SPOKE TO THE POLICE
BRIEFLY AND THEY'RE PLANNING,
OBVIOUSLY, DAYS AND DAYS OF
ASSISTANCE SO THAT EVERYONE IN
THIS COMMUNITY CAN COME TOGETHER
AFTER THESE JUST -- THIS AWFUL,
AWFUL DAY.
AND AFTER SUCH A TRAGIC AND
EMOTIONAL NIGHTMARE FOR THIS
COMMUNITY, YOU KNOW, YOU CAN
UNDERSTAND THAT THEY HAVE A LOT
TO DISCUSS AND A LOT TO GRIEVE
AND PROBABLY WANT TO DO IT
TOGETHER.
ALI?
>> WELL, ONE PARENT WE SPOKE TO
WAS JUST THANKFUL, JOHN, FOR
WHAT THOSE TEACHERS WHO WERE
ABLE TO ABLE TO OFFER THOSE KIDS
COMFORT AND OFFER THEM SOME
PROTECTION, ONE PARENT WAS
REALLY, REALLY GRATEFUL ABOUT
WHAT A TEACHER HAD DONE FOR HER
SON.
>> I'M JUST SO GRATEFUL TO THE
TEACHER WHO SAVED HIM.
>> YOU THINK THE TEACHER SAVED
HIS LIFE?
>> SHE DEFINITELY DID.
HE HAD BULLETS GOING BY HIM AND
GRABBED HIM AND ANOTHER CHILD
AND PULLED HIM INTO A CLASSROOM.
[ Female Announcer ]
IMAGINE SKIN SO HEALTHY,
IT NEVER GETS DRY AGAIN.
CAN YOUR MOISTURIZER DO THAT?
[ Female Announcer ]
DERMATOLOGIST RECOMMENDED
Aveeno HAS AN OAT FORMULA,
NOW PROVEN
TO BUILD A MOISTURE RESERVE,
SO SKIN CAN REPLENISH ITSELF.
THAT'S HEALTHY SKIN FOR LIFE.
ONLY FROM Aveeno.
IS THE SAME FREQUENT HEARTBURN
TREATMENT AS PRILOSEC OTC.
NOW WITH A FANCY COATING
THAT GIVES YOU A BURST
OF WILDBERRY FLAVOR.
NOW WHY MAKE A FLAVORED
HEARTBURN PILL?
BECAUSE THIS IS AMERICA.
AND WE DON'T JUST
MAKE THINGS YOU WANT,
WE MAKE THINGS YOU
DIDN'T EVEN KNOW YOU WANTED.
LIKE A SPOON FORK.
SPRAY CHEESE.
AND JEANS MADE
OUT OF SWEATPANTS.
SO GRAB YOURSELF SOME
NEW PRILOSEC OTC WILDBERRY.
[ Male Announcer ]
ONE PILL EACH MORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBURN.
SATISFACTION GUARANTEED
OR YOUR MONEY BACK.
YOU KNOW, ONE JOB OR THE OTHER.
THE MOMENT I COULD ACCESS
THE RETIREMENT PLAN,
I JUST BECAME FIRM ABOUT IT --
YOU KNOW, IT'S LIKE
IT JUST HITS YOU FAST.
YOU KNOW, YOU START THINKING
ABOUT WHAT'S
REALLY IMPORTANT HERE.
♪
>>> HALF PAST THE HOUR NOW.
WELCOME BACK, EVERYONE.
I'M JOHN BERMAN IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
YOU'RE WATCHING CNN'S SPECIAL
COVERAGE OF THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
WE ARE LIVE THIS MORNING IN
NEWTOWN WHERE YESTERDAY THERE
WAS SO MUCH TRAGEDY.
IN JUST ABOUT 60 MINUTES, WE
EXPECT TO START LEARNING THE
IDENTITIES OF MANY OF THE
VICTIMS HERE IN NEWTOWN.
MEANWHILE, THE COMMUNITY STILL
SEARCHING FOR ANSWERS JUST LIKE
THE POLICE.
JUST LIKE ALL OF US.
THEY'RE ALL LOOKING FOR ANSWERS
TO THE QUESTION WHY.
WHY DID THIS HAPPEN?
WHY DID SOMEONE ATTACK AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL KILLING 26
PEOPLE, 20 OF THEM CHILDREN AGES
5 TO 10 YEARS OLD?
LAST NIGHT THE COMMUNITY
GATHERED TO PAY THEIR RESPECTS.
MANY OF THEM BEHIND ME AT THIS
CHURCH AND TO CONSOLE ONE
ANOTHER.
THEY ALSO SAID GOOD-BYE TO THE
VICTIMS KILLED AT THE SHOOTING,
AT THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
HERE'S JUST A SMALL PIECE OF THE
RADIO TRAFFIC BETWEEN FIRST
RESPONDERS AS THE DETAILS OF THE
SHOOTING REALLY STARTED TO COME
IN.
>> MEDICS, YOU'RE REQUESTED TO
STAGE -- I WILL NEED TWO
AMBULANCES AT THIS TIME.
>> JUST RECEIVED A CALL.
WE HAVE ONE FEMALE IN ROOM ONE
WHO HAS RECEIVED A GUN SHOT
WOUND TO THE FOOT.
>> I NEED UNITS IN THE POOL.
I'VE GOT BODIES HERE.
BE ADVISED, WE DO HAVE MULTIPLE
WEAPONS, INCLUDING RIFLE AND
SHOTGUNS.
>> -- REQUIRE BACKUP AND THEY
SAID CALL FOR EVERYTHING.
>> WHAT IS THE NUMBER OF
AMBULANCES YOU'LL REQUIRE.
>> THEY DON'T KNOW.
THEY ARE NOT GIVING US A NUMBER.
>> FIRE RESCUE 444 RESPOND, 12
DICKINSON DRIVE SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL.
RESPOND, SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
MEDICAL EMERGENCIES.
>> I HAVE MULTIPLE AMBULANCE
PERSONNEL COMING INBOUND.
CAN WE STAGE THE AREA COMMAND
AREA IN THE SCHOOL PARKING AREA?
>> THEY FOUND A CHILLING SCENE,
A HORRIFIC SCENE, THE SCENE
WHICH ALL THE FIRST RESPONDERS
SAY THEY HAVE NEVER SEEN BEFORE.
IT'S A SAFE COMMUNITY.
BEFORE THIS, THEY ONLY HAD ONE
REPORTED HOMICIDE IN THE PAST
TEN YEARS.
BUT NOW, NEWTOWN WILL BE
SYNONYMOUS WITH TOWNS LIKE
COLUMBINE, BLACKSBURG, LIKE
TOWNS WHERE WE'VE SEEN SO MANY
OF THESE TRAGEDIES.
I WANT TO BRING IN MARY SNOW
RIGHT NOW.
AND RIGHT NOW LAW ENFORCEMENT
SOURCES SAY THE SHOOTER WAS
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA AND SAY
THEY FOUND HIS MOTHER'S BODY AT
THE HOME THEY SHARED TOGETHER.
YOU ARE OUTSIDE THAT HOME RIGHT
NOW.
WHAT MORE CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT
THIS INVESTIGATION?
>> Reporter: WELL, JOHN, I CAN
TELL YOU THAT THE POLICE STILL
HAVE BLOCKED OFF THE ROAD
LEADING TO THE LANZA HOME.
AND YESTERDAY S.W.A.T. TEAMS HAD
DESCENDED ON THIS AREA FOR
SEVERAL HOURS.
AND AS YOU MENTIONED, ADAM
LANZA'S MOTHER'S BODY WAS FOUND
AT THE HOME.
AND INVESTIGATORS HAD BEEN
ASKING NEIGHBORS, TRYING TO
PIECE TOGETHER AS MUCH
INFORMATION AS THEY COULD ABOUT
THIS FAMILY.
AND WHAT WE HAVE BEEN HEARING
FROM FORMER CLASSMATES IS THAT
ADAM LANZA WAS DESCRIBED AS A
STUDENT WHO WAS VERY BRIGHT,
VERY QUIET, SOME OF THE
DESCRIPTIONS ABOUT HIM WERE
SOCIALLY AWKWARD.
YESTERDAY, THERE WAS A WOMAN WHO
SAID SHE WAS A FORMER BUS DRIVER
AND KNEW HIM WHEN HE WAS YOUNGER
AND SHE SAID THAT THERE WAS
NOTHING ABOUT HIM THAT REALLY
STOOD OUT.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> HE WAS A NICE KID.
VERY POLITE.
SHE RAISED VERY NICE BOYS, TO
ME.
THAT'S WHY I THINK IT'S A SHOCK.
TO EVEN KNOW THEM AND REALIZE
WHO THEY ARE AND WHAT HE DID.
YOU CAN'T UNDERSTAND WHAT
HAPPENED THAT HE -- THAT HE
SNAPPED WHAT HAVE YOU AND TOOK
SUCH INNOCENT LIVES.
>> AND SOME OF THE NEIGHBORS WHO
KNEW HIM IN RECENT YEARS, SOME
DESCRIBED HIM AS BEING
DIFFERENT.
ONE NEIGHBOR USED THE WORD
TROUBLED TO DESCRIBE HIM, BUT
WOULDN'T REALLY ELABORATE ON
THAT.
JOHN?
>> MARY, THREE GUNS, WE
UNDERSTAND, AT THE SCENE.
TWO HANDGUNS, A CIG SIEOR, A
GLOCK.
DO WE HAVE A SENSE OF WHERE THE
SHOOTER GOT THESE WEAPONS?
>> YEAH, AND VERY STRICT LAWS
HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
AND WHAT WE HAVE LEARNED FROM
OUR OWN SUSAN CANDIOTTI'S
REPORTING IS THAT THESE GUNS
WERE LEGALLY PURCHASED AND
PURCHASED IN THE NAME OF NANCY
LANZA, THE SUSPECT'S MOTHER.
>> Reporter: NANCY LANZA FOR
MUCH OF THE DAY YESTERDAY,
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN REPORTING SHE
WORKED AT THE SCHOOL.
THERE APPEAR TO BE QUESTIONS
ABOUT THAT.
WHAT MORE HAVE YOU LEARNED ABOUT
HER LIFESTYLE, ANYTHING FROM THE
NEIGHBORS WHO MAY KNOW HER?
>> YEAH, AND YOU KNOW, JOHN, AS
YOU SAID, THIS IS A TIGHT-KNIT
COMMUNITY AND SO MANY OF THE
PEOPLE HERE HAVE SENT THEIR
CHILDREN TO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AND WE COULD FIND NO ONE WHO
COULD PLACE HER AT THE SCHOOL OR
SAY THAT THERE WAS A DEFINITIVE
LINK.
WE DID MEET ONE NEIGHBOR WHO HAD
KNOWN HER IN THE PAST,
DESCRIBING HER AS A GOOD MOTHER.
SHE WAS -- HER BELIEF THAT SHE
WAS A STAY-AT-HOME MOM AND WAS
UNAWARE OF ANY JOBS THAT SHE
HELD.
SO IT'S REALLY UNCLEAR ABOUT,
YOU KNOW, HER PROFESSION OR IF
THERE WAS ANY LINK TO THE
SCHOOL.
>> MARY SNOW, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
YOU'VE BEEN HERE SINCE EARLY
YESTERDAY WORKING ON THIS STORY.
IT'S HARD FOR EVERYONE INVOLVED.
THANKS, MARY.
ALI?
>> JOHN, MARY WAS AT THAT CHURCH
YOU'RE AT NOW.
ONE OF THE SEVERAL VIGILS THAT
TOOK PLACE AROUND HERE.
IT'S SUCH A SMALL TOWN.
AND YET THERE ARE SO MANY POINTS
OF CONCENTRATION AROUND HERE.
IN FACT, AS YOU PLAYED THAT TAPE
OF THE COMMUNICATION BETWEEN
FIRST RESPONDERS YESTERDAY, YOU
TALKED ABOUT THEM, THEY TALKED
ABOUT A STAGING AREA.
ONE OF THE THINGS THEY DID EARLY
BECAUSE THIS IS A SMALL TOWN
WITH SMALL STREETS, NARROW
STREETS THAT CAN ACCOMMODATE THE
INFLUX OF MEDIA THAT HAVE COME
IN TO COVER IT.
THEY PUT US ALL AT A PARK, TREAD
WELL PARK, IT'S FOOTBALL
FIELD -- SOCCER FIELD IN FRONT
OF ME RIGHT NOW.
THE SCHOOL IS BEHIND US AND THIS
IS A SPACE WHERE EVERYBODY'S
CONVERGED.
JUST BESIDE ME IN ABOUT AN HOUR,
THEY'LL HOLD THE NEWS
CONFERENCES.
THEY WERE HOLDING THEM ELSEWHERE
TODAY AND THEY DECIDED THIS IS
WHERE EVERYBODY IS AND THIS IS
WHERE THEY'RE GOING TO START
LETTING EVERYBODY KNOW WHAT'S
GOING ON.
WHAT WE ARE EXPECTING AT 8:00
EASTERN IS THE RELEASE OF SOME
NAMES.
WE HAVE BEEN REPORTING IT'S ADAM
LANZA, THE SHOOTER, BUT POLICE
HAVE NOT OFFERED THAT
IDENTIFICATION AS OF YET.
THEY WANT POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATIONS ON THE SHOOTER
AND THE VICTIMS.
SO THEY'LL BE BRINGING THAT TO
US.
WE EXPECT AT 8:00 OR SOME TIME
THEREAFTER.
REMEMBER, THERE WERE 18 CHILDREN
SHOT IN THE SCHOOL, SIX ADULTS,
TWO OF THE CHILDREN DIED AT THE
HOSPITAL.
ONE PERSON REMAINS WOUNDED AND
IN THE HOSPITAL.
NOW IT'S BEEN OVER 21 HOURS
SINCE THIS UNIMAGINABLE
NIGHTMARE HAPPENED HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
ALL STARTED WHEN A GUNMAN
ENTERED THROUGH THE DOORS OF
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
TOM FOREMAN WALKS US THROUGH
WHAT HAPPENED MINUTE BY MINUTE.
>> THIS IS WHAT WE KNOW AT THIS
POINT ABOUT THE TIME LINE OF THE
SHOOTING AS REPORTED BY LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS AND
WITNESSES.
AND THE LAYOUT OF THE SCHOOL AS
BEST WE CAN PIECE IT ALL
TOGETHER.
9:30 IN THE MORNING, CLASSES
UNDERWAY FOR HALF AN HOUR.
MORE THAN 600 STUDENTS AND ABOUT
50 FACULTY MEMBERS ARE INSIDE
THE BUILDING.
IN ADDITION TO THAT, A MEETING
CONVENED BY SOME SCHOOL
OFFICIALS, INCLUDING THE
PRINCIPAL -- ABOUT SEVEN OF THEM
GATHERED IN ONE ROOM.
ABOUT 9:40, TEN MINUTES LATER AS
BEST WE CAN MAKE IT OUT AGAIN,
THAT'S WHEN THE GUNMAN APPEARS
TO HAVE ENTERED THE BUILDING.
HOW?
WE DON'T KNOW, THEY HAD A NEW
SECURITY SYSTEM THAT MIGHT HAVE
KEPT HIM OUT.
NOT SURE WHAT HAPPENED WITH
THAT.
POLICE SPENT A LOT OF TIME
LOOKING AT A CAR PARKED RIGHT
OUT HERE IN THE FIRE LANE
SUGGESTING THAT IF THAT WERE HIS
CAR THAT, IN FACT, HE MAY HAVE
INDEED COME RIGHT THROUGH THE
FRONT DOOR HERE INTO THE SCHOOL.
PEOPLE THROUGHOUT THE BUILDING
AT THAT POINT START SAYING THAT
THEY'RE HEARING SHOTS.
9:41, THE CALLS START GOING IN
TO 911 AT THAT POINT.
AND THE PRINCIPAL, THE VICE
PRINCIPAL, AND THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST ALL GO TOWARD THE
GUNFIRE OUT IN THE HALLWAY
ACCORDING TO A WITNESS.
ONLY THE VICE PRINCIPAL RETURNS,
AND THE VICE PRINCIPAL IS
WOUNDED.
THERE ARE MANY, MANY SHOTS OUT
THERE.
EVERYONE SAYS THEY HEAR IT.
AUTHORITIES SAY THE SHOOTING
ITSELF HAPPENED IN A RELATIVELY
SHORT PERIOD OF TIME, AND THEY
SAY THE GUNMAN GENERALLY STAYS
IN THIS AREA.
IN FACT, THEY SAY ALL THE
SHOOTING HAPPENS IN TWO ROOMS.
9:45, TEACHERS THROUGHOUT THIS
BUILDING ARE TRYING TO PROTECT
STUDENTS, IN SOME CASES THE
STUDENTS SAY THEY HELPED THEM
HIDE, IN OTHERS THERE SEEMS TO
BE SOME INDICATION THAT TEACHERS
MAY HAVE TRIED TO GET THEM OUT
OF THE BUILDING.
THE BOTTOM LINE IS, THOUGH, YOU
SEE THE PICTURES OF THE NEWTOWN
BEE, THERE WAS AN EFFORT TO GET
THE STUDENTS OUT TO SAFETY.
AND IT WAS A DIFFICULT STUNT TO
PULL OFF BECAUSE YOU HAVE
HUNDREDS OF KIDS HERE AND
THEY'RE OBVIOUSLY TRAUMATIZED
AND VERY, VERY UPSET.
9:50.
BY THIS TIME FOR SURE, AND
AGAIN, WE'RE NOT SURE OF THE
TIME LINE, IT'S MURKY, BUT THE
GUNMAN SOMEWHERE IN THIS PROCESS
HAS DIED.
POLICE OFFICERS SAY NO OFFICER
FIRED A SHOT.
SO IT'S BELIEVED HE SHOT
HIMSELF, BUT THIS WE DO KNOW.
AS OFFICERS ARRIVE ON THE SCENE
FROM STATE AND LOCAL POLICE,
THEY SECURE THE ENTIRE BUILDING
AND THEY SPREAD OUT THROUGH IT
TRYING TO MAKE SURE THERE ARE NO
OTHER GUNMEN AND TRYING TO FIND
ALL THESE POCKETS OF CHILDREN
HIDING WITHIN THIS BUILDING.
AND AT THAT POINT, THEY START
ESCORTING THEM OUT OF THE
BUILDING AS WELL.
A DIFFICULT, DIFFICULT TIME, AND
THIS TIME LINE IS WHAT THE
INVESTIGATORS ARE GOING TO HAVE
TO BUILD UPON IN THE COMING
WEEKS TO CLARIFY, TO MAKE SURE
WE KNOW EXACTLY WHEN THINGS
HAPPENED AND HOW.
>> Reporter: AND THAT IS TOM
FOREMAN REPORTING FOR CNN.
IN THE AFTERMATH OF FRIDAY'S
TRAGEDY, QUESTIONS ARE BEING
FORMED AROUND THE GUNS THAT WERE
USED.
THREE WEAPONS WERE RECOVERED
FROM THE SCENE.
SIMILAR TO THE ONES WE'RE ABOUT
TO SHOW YOU.
THEY INCLUDE TWO PISTOLS, A
GLOCK AND A SIG SIEOR.
A BUSH MASTER RIFLE.
ALL THREE GUNS WERE LEGALLY
PURCHASED BY THE SHOOTER'S
MOTHER.
LET'S DISCUSS THIS A LITTLE
MORE.
WE'RE JOINED BY TOM FUENTES.
TOM, LET'S START WITH YOU.
THE BUSH MASTER WAS REGISTERED
TO THE SUSPECT'S MOTHER, NANCY
LANZ, A SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPON IN
A STATE THAT IS CALLED A MAY
ISSUE STATE.
IT'S NOT THE EASIEST PLACE TO
GET A GUN.
PARTICULARLY A SEMIAUTOMATIC
GUN.
EXPLAIN WHY WE THINK NANCY LANZA
HAD A BUSH MASTER AND WAS ABLE
TO GET ONE.
>> GOOD MORNING, ALI.
I THINK RIGHT NOW THERE'S NO
CLUE WHY SHE WOULD'VE GOTTEN
THOSE WEAPONS.
SHE MAY HAVE BEEN IN FEAR OF
BEING BURGLARIZED OR ROBBED OR
SOMEBODY ELSE HAPPENING.
MAYBE SHE HAD BEEN THREATENED,
YOU KNOW, ONCE BEFORE IN HER
LIFE AND FELT LIKE SHE WANTED
WEAPONS IN THE HOUSE TO PROTECT
HERSELF.
BUT, THERE'S NOT GOING TO BE AN
EASY ANSWER TO THAT QUESTION
UNLESS SHE TOLD A FRIEND OR
RELATIVE WHY SHE WANTED TO HAVE
THOSE THREE WEAPONS.
>> YOU KNOW, LET ME FOLLOW UP,
TOM.
HOW HARD IS IT TO GET A BUSH
MASTER RIFLE?
AND IF I CAN ASK ABOUT THE
PISTOLS FOR A SECOND, WHAT ARE
THE ISSUES SURROUNDING THEM?
ARE THEY POSSIBLE TO LOAD WITH
THESE HIGH NUMBER OF ROUND
MAGAZINES WITH A LOT OF BULLETS?
>> YES, THEY'RE POSSIBLE TO DO
THAT.
THE STANDARD MAGAZINE WOULD
GENERALLY ENABLE THAT GUN TO
HAVE ABOUT 15 BULLETS IN IT.
EACH OF THE TWO GUNS, ABOUT 15
BULLETS A PIECE, BUT YOU CAN BUY
EXTENDED MAGAZINES THAT CARRY 30
ROUNDS LIKE WE SAW IN THE TUCSON
SHOOTING A COUPLE YEARS AGO.
THAT WOULD BE AVAILABLE.
WE DON'T KNOW IF HE HAD THAT IN
THIS CASE OR IF HE JUST RELOADED
AND HAD MULTIPLE MAGAZINES AND
RELOADED AS HE RAN OUT.
BECAUSE WE THINK HE SHOT MORE
THAN 30 ROUNDS FROM THE TWO
PISTOLS.
>> TOM, THESE PISTOLS ARE
COMMON.
THEY ARE ACTUALLY COMMONLY USED
BY POLICE, PARTICULARLY THAT
GLOCK.
BUSH MASTER BIT MORE OF AN
UNUSUAL WEAPON.
BUT IF CIVILIANS ARE GOING TO
GET PISTOLS, THESE ARE THE TWO
MORE COMMON ONES AROUND.
>> WELL, IN SENSE, THEY'RE NOT
AS COMMON BECAUSE OF THE FACT
THEY'RE HIGH-QUALITY GUNS THAT
ARE MORE EXPENSIVE THAN THE
AVERAGE PISTOLE.
OBVIOUSLY PROFESSIONAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICERS WOULD WANT
TO HAVE A QUALITY PISTOL SUCH AS
A GLOCK OR SIG SAUER.
THESE ARE QUALITY WEAPONS, YOU
KNOW, AS WE'VE SEEN,
UNFORTUNATELY, WHEN BROUGHT TO A
BAD PURPOSE.
AS FAR AS THE BUSH MASTER,
AGAIN, THESE GUNS ARE LEGAL.
ANY RESTRICTIONS ON ASSAULT
RIFLES THAT HAD BEEN IN PLACE
HAVE EXPIRED OR NOT RENEWED BY
THE CONGRESS.
SO PRETTY MUCH ANYBODY CAN GO IF
THEY MEET THE GUN CHECKS CAN GO
AHEAD AND PURCHASE THIS.
AND IN THIS SITUATION, NO MATTER
HOW MENTALLY ILL THE SHOOTER MAY
HAVE BEEN, THERE'S NO INDICATION
THAT HIS MOTHER WAS OR THAT SHE
HAD ANY TROUBLE PURCHASING THE
WEAPONS, REGISTERING THE
WEAPONS, OR HAVING THEM.
YOU STILL HAVE THE ISSUE OF A
MENTALLY DISTURBED PERSON IN A
HOME WHERE THE HOMEOWNER IN THIS
CASE THE MOTHER LEGALLY OWNS
WEAPONS.
>> AND WE'RE STILL WAITING TO
FIND OUT IF, IN FACT, THERE'S --
SORRY, JOHN, GO AHEAD.
>> NO, I WAS JUST GOING TO SAY
YOU MENTIONED BEFORE THE NUMBER
OF SHOTS FIRED.
WE BELIEVE WE HEAR FROM
WITNESSES THEY HEARD AT LEAST
100 ROUNDS GO OFF IN THE
HALLWAY.
YOU TALKED ABOUT THE NUMBER OF
BULLETS THESE COULD HOLD THE 30
MAGAZINES IF THEY HAD EXTENDED
CLIPS.
HOW HARD WOULD IT BE TO GET OFF
100 ROUNDS IN THIS TYPE OF
EVENT?
>> AS QUICKLY AS YOU CAN PULL
THE TRIGGER AND RELOAD
MAGAZINES.
WHEN SOMEBODY RUNS OUT OF
AMMUNITION, WHICH DOESN'T OFTEN
HAPPEN IN THE MOVIES, BUT WHEN
THAT HAPPENS AND THEY RELOAD THE
MAGAZINE, ONE OF THE VICTIMS MAY
POUNCE ON THE SHOOTER AND ATTACK
HIM AT THAT POINT WHEN HE'S
VULNERABLE.
BUT HERE WE'RE TALKING 5 AND
6-YEAR-OLDS.
SO EVEN IF HE STOPS FOR TWO
SECONDS TO SWITCH MAGAZINES AND
PUT A FRESH MAGAZINE IN THE GUN
TO KEEP GOING, THE LITTLE KIDS
AREN'T GOING TO BE ABLE TO STOP
HIM.
SO THIS IS A WHOLE DIFFERENT
SITUATION THAN WE HAVE IF IT
OCCURRED ON A CITY STREET CORNER
OR EVEN WITH ADULTS.
>> TOM, IN CONNECTICUT, AS WE
SAID, THIS IS A -- IT'S CALLED A
MAY ISSUE STATE.
WHICH MEANS IF YOU FULFILL THE
REQUIREMENTS REQUIRED TO GET A
GUN, THEY HAVE OTHER THINGS THEY
CAN DO TO DETERMINE WHETHER
SOMEONE SHOULD OR SHOULD NOT
HAVE ACCESS TO A GUN.
HOW DOES THAT WORK?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, IN THIS CASE,
IF THE MOTHER HAS NEVER BEEN
ARRESTED OR JUDGED MENTALLY ILL
AND SHE WANTS TO PURCHASE A
WEAPON, SHE GOES THROUGH THE
PROCEDURES IN PLACE IN THE STATE
OF CONNECTICUT, WHICH ARE
REPORTEDLY MORE STRINGENT THAN
MANY OF THE OTHER STATES WHERE
THESE TYPE OF SHOOTINGS HAVE
OCCURRED.
BUT IF SHE'S IN A POSITION TO GO
AHEAD AND BUY THAT WEAPON OR
THREE WEAPONS LEGALLY, YOU KNOW,
IT DOESN'T -- THAT DOESN'T SOLVE
THE PROBLEM.
SHE'S GOT THE GUNS THAT ARE IN
THE HOUSE, YOU KNOW, IT JUST
TOOK HER SON TO STEAL THEM FROM
HER AND TURN THEM ON HER AND GO
FORWARD.
>> TOM, THANKS FOR YOUR INPUT
INTO THIS, FORMER ASSISTANT FBI
DIRECTOR JOINING US NOW.
IN WASHINGTON, A VISIBLY
EMOTIONAL AND TEARFUL PRESIDENT
OBAMA ADDRESSED THE NATION
YESTERDAY AFTERNOON.
HE OFFERED PRAYERS, SOLACE AND
SUPPORT FOR THE VICTIMS IN THIS
TRAGEDY.
>> WE'VE ENDURED TOO MANY OF
THESE TRAGEDIES IN THE PAST FEW
YEARS.
I KNOW THERE'S NOT A PARENT IN
AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS, MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES TO HELPING
OUR CHILDREN FULFILL THEIR
DREAMS.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN FOR THE
PARENTS OF THE SURVIVORS, AS
WELL.
FOR AS BLESSED AS THEY ARE TO
HAVE THEIR CHILDREN HOME
TONIGHT, THEY KNOW THEIR
CHILDREN'S INNOCENCE HAS BEEN
TORN AWAY FROM THEM TOO EARLY
AND THERE ARE NO WORDS THAT WILL
EASE THEIR PAIN.
THIS EVENING, MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO I KNOW WHAT EVERY PARENT
IN AMERICA WILL DO WHICH IS HUG
OUR CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER
AND TELL THEM WE LOVE THEM.
AND WE'LL REMIND EACH OTHER HOW
DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT.
MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF THE
VICTIMS.
AND IN THE WORDS OF SCRIPTURE,
HEAL THE BROKEN HEARTED AND BIND
UP THEIR WOUNDS.
[ sniffs ] I HAVE A COLD.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
I HEARD YOU GUYS CAN SHIP GROUND
FOR LESS THAN THE UPS STORE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I'VE LEARNED THE ONLY WAY TO GET
A HOLIDAY DEAL IS TO CAMP OUT.
YOU KNOW WE'VE BEEN OPEN
ALL NIGHT.
IS THIS A TRICK
TO GET MY SPOT?
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SAVE ON GROUND SHIPPING
AT FEDEX OFFICE.
>>> I WOULD LIKE TO SHARE A
LETTER FROM HIS HOLINESS, POPE
BENEDICT XVI WHO SENT HIS
CONDOLENCES FROM THE VATICAN.
>> I WAS PROMPTLY INFORMED OF
THE SHOOTING AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
I CONVEY MY HEART FELT GRIEF AND
THE ASSURANCE OF MY PERSONAL
PRAYERS TO THE VICTIMS AND THEIR
FAMILIES, TO ALL THOSE OF THE
COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN AND
ESPECIALLY THE PARISH OF ST.
ROSE OF LIMA.
IN THE AFTERMATH OF THE
SENSELESS TRAGEDY, I ASK GOD OUR
FATHER TO CONSOLE ALL THOSE WHO
MOURN AND TO SUSTAIN THE ENTIRE
COMMUNITY WITH THE SPIRITUAL
STRENGTH WHICH TRIUMPHS OVER
VIOLENCE BY THE POWER
FORGIVENESS, HOPE, AND
RECONCILING LOVE.
WITH GRATITUDE, FOR YOUR
PRAYERS, AND YOUR PRESENCE, I
REMAIN YOURS IN CHRIST, BENEDICT
XVI.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYONE, TO
OUR SPECIAL COVERAGE OF THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTING.
I'M JOHN BERMAN.
THIS MORNING AT 8:00 EASTERN
TIME, WE'RE ANTICIPATING A LIVE
NEWS CONFERENCE HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WHERE AUTHORITIES
ARE EXPECTED TO RELEASE THE
NAMES OF THE CHILDREN AND THE
ADULTS KILLED AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
I WANT TO BRING IN RIGHT NOW
DECLAN, A PARENT IN THIS
COMMUNITY.
HIS 8-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER SURVIVED
THE SHOOTING AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL YESTERDAY.
AND LET ME START OFF BY SAYING,
FIRST OF ALL, OUR THOUGHTS ARE
WITH YOU AND THIS ENTIRE TOWN,
WHAT YOU'RE ALL GOING THROUGH
RIGHT NOW.
LET ME ASK YOU, HOW ARE YOU?
AND HOW'S YOUR DAUGHTER?
>> MY DAUGHTER IS DOING
SURPRISINGLY WELL.
SHE'S DOING SURPRISINGLY WELL
AFTER WHAT SHE SAW.
>> HOW DID THIS GO DOWN FOR YOU
YESTERDAY?
WHEN DID YOU FIRST GET WORD THAT
SOMETHING HORRIBLE WAS HAPPENING
AT THE SCHOOL?
WHAT DID THEY TELL YOU?
AND WHAT DID THEY ASK YOU TO DO?
>> I WORKED ABOUT AN HOUR PLUS
AWAY AND MY WIFE CALLED ME AND
SAID THERE'D BEEN A SHOOTING.
SHE HAD ALREADY RUSHED TO THE
SCHOOL TO GET MY DAUGHTER WHO
HAD MADE THEIR WAY TO THE FIRE
HOUSE.
I WAS ABLE TO GET TO THE FIRE
HOUSE EVENTUALLY AND AT THAT
TIME, IT WAS JUST TOO EARLY.
WE HAD NO IDEA ABOUT ALL THE
CHILDREN AND THE FACULTY WHO HAD
DIED.
>> YOU KNEW YOUR DAUGHTER WAS
OKAY, THOUGH, CORRECT?
>> THANK GOD.
WE KNEW SHE WAS OKAY AND, YOU
KNOW, JUST GAVE HER A BIG HUG.
YOU KNOW, AND JUST GOT HER OUT
OF THERE.
>> AND SO MANY PARENTS ACROSS
THE COUNTRY INCLUDING ME,
FRANKLY, WANT TO KNOW HOW TO
TALK TO OUR KIDS ABOUT THIS.
OUR KIDS, OF COURSE, DIDN'T GO
THROUGH THIS.
HAS YOUR DAUGHTER ASKED YOU ANY
QUESTIONS ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED?
>> WELL, THAT'S A VERY DIFFICULT
QUESTION.
AND, YOU KNOW, VERY -- THIS IS
ALL NEW.
SO ALL WE REALLY CAN DO, I
THINK, IS THE BEST THING IS TO
BE HONEST AND LET HER KNOW WHAT
WE KNOW.
TRY TO TALK TO THEM AND TRY TO
REINFORCE THE BAD GUY THAT DID
THIS IS GONE FOREVER.
BECAUSE, OF COURSE, ALL THEY'RE
TALKING ABOUT IS NOT WANTING TO
GO TO SCHOOL AGAIN.
BOTH MY CHILDREN.
I HAVE A 10-YEAR-OLD WHO WAS IN
ANOTHER SCHOOL ON LOCKDOWN, AS
WELL.
AND THEY'RE JUST REALLY, REALLY
FREAKED OUT.
AS YOU CAN IMAGINE.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
THEY'RE TALKING TO YOU, THEY
DON'T WANT TO GO BACK TO SCHOOL
AGAIN.
DID YOUR DAUGHTER TELL YOU
ANYTHING ABOUT WHAT IT WAS LIKE
TO BE IN THE SCHOOL AS THIS WAS
HAPPENING?
>> SHE WAS IN A READING CLASS,
AND IT WAS A SEPARATED CLASS
WITH JUST -- USUALLY THERE'S
JUST A FEW KIDS IN THERE.
AND SHE HEARD A BUNCH OF
BANGING, SOUNDED LIKE HAMMERING
SHE SAID.
AND HER TEACHER, HER READING
TEACHER GRABBED MY DAUGHT AS
WELL AS A FELLOW TEACHER THAT
WAS IN THE READING ROOM AND
ACTUALLY LOCKED THEM IN THE
BATHROOM AND THEY JUST HEARD
LOTS OF SHOTS AND I THINK MY
DAUGHTER SAID SHE HEARD
SCREAMING.
AND EVENTUALLY THE POLICE WERE
BANGING ON THE DOOR AND WERE
ABLE TO ESCORT THEM INTO THE
HALLWAY, GET THEM OUT TOWARDS,
UNFORTUNATELY, WHERE FROM WHAT I
UNDERSTAND WHERE MOST OF THE
SHOOTINGS HAPPENED, WHICH WAS A
PRETTY ROUGH SCENE FROM WHAT I
UNDERSTAND FROM WHAT MY DAUGHTER
TOLD ME.
AND THEN THEY WERE ABLE TO WHISK
THEM AWAY TO THE FIRE HOUSE.
AND I BELIEVE MY DAUGHTER, FROM
WHAT SHE TELLS ME WAS THE FIR
FIRST -- THE FIRST KID TO GET TO
THE FIRE HOUSE.
>> THIS IS SOMETHING NO KID
SHOULD EVER HAVE TO GO THROUGH,
DECLAN, I THINK THAT GOES
WITHOUT SAYING.
WHAT KIND OF COMMUNICATION ARE
YOU GETTING FROM THE TOWN, FROM
THE AUTHORITIES?
>> YOU KNOW, I'VE GOT TO BE
FRANK WITH YOU, SINCE THIS
HAPPENED, YOU KNOW, THE PHONE'S
BEEN RINGING OFF THE HOOK.
YOU KNOW, PEOPLE ARE WANTING TO
KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON.
SO THERE'S JUST BEEN -- WE
ACTUALLY TURNED OUR PHONES OFF
YESTERDAY.
LAST NIGHT, AND WE'VE BEEN JUST
GETTING OUR SOURCES FROM THE
NEWS.
WE HAVEN'T LET OUR KIDS WATCH
THE NEWS YET.
I DON'T KNOW IF THAT'S THE RIGHT
OR WRONG DECISION, BUT I THINK
IT'S BEST THAT WE TALK WITH THEM
FIRST AND THEY'RE GOING TO GET
PLENTY OF THAT STUFF LATER.
AND SO, YOU KNOW, NEWS SOURCES
LIKE YOURS IS WHERE WE'RE
GETTING OUR UPDATES.
>> DECLAN, WE SINCERELY
APPRECIATE YOU TALKING TO US
THIS MORNING.
WHAT ARE YOUR PLANS FOR THE
WEEKEND AT THIS POINT?
HOW DO YOU -- HOW DO YOU SPEND
THE NEXT TWO DAYS?
>> I HONESTLY HAVEN'T EVEN
THOUGHT ABOUT IT.
THIS IS SO NEW.
MOST OF MY DAY YESTERDAY WAS
JUST SPENT -- YOU KNOW, WE
GOT -- IT WASN'T THAT EASY TO
GET OUT OF THE AREA.
THERE WERE LOTS OF EMERGENCY
VEHICLES, POLICE VEHICLES, YOU
KNOW, AS YOU CAN IMAGINE.
SO A LOT OF THE DAY WAS SPENT
GETTING OUT OF THERE.
AND THEN I GOT MY WIFE AND MY
DAUGHTER HOME AND HAD TO GO TO
THE OTHER SCHOOL TO GET MY SON
OUT OF LOCKDOWN AND WE HAD TO
WAIT FOR THAT.
AND THEN WE FINALLY GOT HOME.
AND I JUST SAID, LOOK, WE NEED A
QUIET NIGHT TOGETHER AS A FAMILY
AND PRAY FOR THOSE POOR KIDS AND
THOSE POOR FACULTY MEMBERS WHO
WE KNOW SO MANY OF THEM.
AND I HAVE NO IDEA WHEN THE
NAMES COME OUT, BUT IT'S JUST
SOMETHING THAT RIGHT NOW I CAN'T
EVEN FATHOM WHEN THEY RELEASE
THE NAMES OF THOSE CHILDREN WHO
I'M SURE WE ALL -- WE KNOW AND
WE KNOW THEIR FAMILIES AND THE
FACULTY MEMBERS AND, SO, I
REALLY DON'T HAVE A PLAN IS TO
ANSWER YOUR QUESTION.
>> PLEASE KNOW THAT ALL OF OUR
THOUGHTS ARE WITH YOU.
THE ENTIRE COUNTRY'S THOUGHTS
ARE WITH YOU AND YOUR COMMUNITY
THIS MORNING.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR BEING WITH
US.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR BEING SO
STRONG.
>> I REALLY APPRECIATE IT.
THANK YOU.
>> ALI?
>> JOHN, TOUGH CONVERSATION TO
LISTEN TO.
AND WHAT HE SAID, WHAT DECLAN
SAID, IT'S GOING TO BE SO HARD
WHEN THE NAMES COME OUT BECAUSE
PEOPLE DID TRY AND HAVE A QUIET
NIGHT LAST NIGHT.
THEY DON'T KNOW THE NAMES.
THE PARENTS WHO DIDN'T GET THEIR
KIDS BACK KNOW WHO THEY ARE,
KNOW WHO THEIR KIDS ARE.
EVERYBODY ELSE DOESN'T.
THIS MORNING AT 8:00 A.M.
EASTERN, WE ARE ANTICIPATING A
LIVE NEWS CONFERENCE HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WHERE
AUTHORITIES ARE EXPECTED TO
RELEASE THE NAMES OF THE
CHILDREN AND THE ADULTS, THE SIX
ADULTS KILLED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
LET'S CHECK IN NOW WITH NICK
VALENCIA IN ATLANTA.
WE KNOW THE SCHOOL PRINCIPAL WAS
ONE OF THE ADULTS KILLED ALONG
WITH THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST.
I UNDERSTAND THAT A PARENT WAS
WITH THEM IN AN OFFICE WHEN THE
GUNMAN OPENED FIRE INSIDE THE