♪ WAS GRACE THAT TAUGHT MY HEART
TO FEEL AND GRACE MY FEARS
RELIEVED ♪
♪ HOW PRECIOUS DID THAT GRACE
APPEAR, THE HOUR I FIRST
BELIEVED ♪
>>> OUTFRONT NEXT HONORING THE
HEROES OF THE NEWTOWN SCHOOL
SHOOTING AND REMEMBERS LOVED
ONES TAKEN TOO EARLY.
A BLOGGER WRITES A PIECE THAT
WAS ENTITLED I AM ADAM LANZA'S
MOTHER AND IGNITED A FIRE STORM.
THAT MOM ANSWERS CRITICS
TONIGHT.
LET'S GO OUT FRONT.
GOOD EVENING, EVERYONE.
I AM ERIN BURNETT.
OUT FRONT TONIGHT, THE GRIEVING
COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT BEGAN BURYING LOVED
ONES TODAY.
FUNERALS WERE HELD FOR TWO
6-YEAR-OLD BOYS, JACK PINTO AND
NOAH POZNER.
JUST MOMENTS AGO WE WERE
APPROACHED BY A REPRESENTATIVE
FOR THE FAMILY OF 6-YEAR-OLD
MADELEINE HSU.
I WILL QUOTE THE WORDS.
SHE WAS SWEET, UNIQUE, BRIGHT,
SPARKLING, DETERMINED LITTLE
GIRL.
SHE WAS AN AVID READER WHO LOVED
RUNNING AND DANCING AND SHE WAS
A BORN LEADER.
THIS IS THE START OF WHAT WILL
BE A VERY PAINFUL WEEK AS
FRIENDS AND FAMILY HERE PREPARE
TO SAY GOODBYE, TO TRY TO SAY
GOODBYE TO THE 20 CHILDREN AND
SIX EDUCATORS KILLED ON FRIDAY
IN THE SECOND WORST SHOOTING IN
AMERICAN HISTORY.
AS NEWTOWN MOURNS, INVESTIGATORS
ARE STILL TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT MOTIVATED ADAM LANZA TO GO
ON A SHOOTING SPREE AND KILL
CHILDREN AND TAKE THE LIFE OF
HIS OWN MOTHER.
WE'LL HAVE MORE IN A MOMENT.
THE TRUTH IS WE MAY NEVER KNOW
WHY ADAM LANZA MAY CHOOSE TO GO
ON A MASS KILLING SPREE, WHY HE
MAY CHOOSE TO GO INTO A SCHOOL
AND KILL INNOCENT 6 AND
7-YEAR-OLDS.
WE ARE LEARNING A LOT MORE ABOUT
HIS MOTHER NANCY AND THE
RELATIONSHIP SHE HAD WITH HER
TROUBLED SON.
ACCORDING TO FRIENDS THE
52-YEAR-OLD DIVORCED MOTHER WAS
TWO WAS DEVOTED TO HER CHILDREN
AND ESPECIALLY CLOSE WITH ADAM
WHO FRIENDS SAY WAS VERY
INTELLIGENT AND SOCIALLY
AWKWARD.
A RETIRED STOCKBROKER, NANCY
LANZA WAS A LIFELONG RED SOX FAN
WITH SEASON TICKETS WHO LIVED
WITH HER SON ADAM IN A LARGE
COLONIAL HOME AND FRIENDS SAY
SHE WAS A LITTLE CONTRADICTION,
EXTREMELY GENEROUS AND FRIENDLY
YET EXTREMELY PRIVATE WHEN IT
CAME TO HER FAMILY LIFE.
THEY SAY SHE DID TALK ABOUT THE
CHALLENGES SHE FACED RAISING A
SON WITH ASPERGER'S SYNDROME AND
HER FRIENDS SAY SHE THOUGHT SHE
MAY SOON BE LEAVING NEWTOWN.
>> SHE WAS TALKING ABOUT
WASHINGTON STATE AND READY TO
CHANGE HER WHOLE LIFE, SELL HER
HOUSE AND START OVER, JUST FOR
HIM, JUST SO HE COULD GO TO
SCHOOL AND HE WAS HER LIFE.
>> FRIENDS SAY NANCE ALANZA WAS
A GUN ENTHUSIAST AND HAD TAKEN
UP TARGET SHOOTING AS A HOBBY
AND THEY INSIST SHE WAS ALWAYS
RESPONSIBLE WITH GUNS.
>> THEY PAINTED HER AS SOME
IRRESPONSIBLE GUN FREAK AND SHE
WASN'T.
SHE WAS THE EPITOME OF
RESPONSIBILITY AND SHE WAS A
PARAGON FOR GUN SAFETY AND
TAUGHT THE BOYS HOW TO USE THE
GUNS RESPONSIBLY.
>> LITTLE DID SHE KNOW THE SON
SHE DOTED ON AND TAUGHT HOW TO
USE GUNS WOULD TURN THOSE GUNS
ON HER AND CHILDREN.
THEY BELIEVE HE SHOT AND KILLED
HIS MOTHER AS SHE WAS LYING IN
BED BEFORE TAKING HER GUNS, TWO
OF HER HANDGUNS AND AN ASSAULT
RIFLE.
I SAT DOWN WITH SOME OF NANCY'S
FRIENDS AT ONE OF HER FAVORITE
RESTAURANTS, A PLACE SHE WENT TO
TWO OR THREE TIMES A WEEK.
IT IS CALLED MY PLACE AND I
ASKED THEM ABOUT WHO WAS NANCY
LANZA?
>> 12 YEARS AGO, 12, 15 YEARS
AGO, MET HER HERE IN THE BAR.
SHE WOULD COME IN AND TAKE OUT
FOOD AND WE GOT TO KNOW EACH
OTHER AND WITH MARK AND WE WOULD
TALK IN THE BAR AND JUST LIKE
CLICKED.
THAT WAS IT.
WE STARTED TALKING AND WE BECAME
GOOD FRIENDS.
>> GOT TO KNOW HER?
>> YEAH.
SHE WAS LIKE I SAID STARTED
COMING INTO THE TAKEOUT AREA AND
PICKING UP FOOD AND GOT TO KNOW
THE FAMILY PRETTY WELL AND VERY
FRIENDLY AND OUT GOING AND FUNNY
AND WE TOOK TO HER, SO, YEAH,
SHE JUST BECAME FAST FRIENDS
WITH US.
SHE DID A LOT IN TOWN AND WAS
ALWAYS ON THE GO.
>> HOW OFTEN DID SHE COME IN?
SOUNDS LIKE YOU KNOW HER WELL.
>> TWO OR THREE TIMES A WEEK.
>> FOR GOOD ESPECIALLY.
THE BAR, NOT SO OFTEN, YOU KNOW.
>> TICKETS FOR A BALL GAME AND
BOSTON GAMES AND STUFF.
>> SEASON TICKETS TO THE RED SOX
AND WOULD INVITE US OR GIVE US
HER TICKETS.
>> WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME SHE
CAME IN.
>> I SAW HER LAST WEEK OR TWO
WEEKS AGO TO TOPS AND SHE CAME
IN AND I WAS TALKING TO HER FOR
A LITTLE BIT.
YEAH.
SHE CAME IN MORE TO PICK UP FOOD
THAN ANYTHING ELSE.
>> NOW, YOU DIDN'T MEET THE
BOYS, RIGHT?
>> YEAH.
>> YOU KNEW ONE OF THEM.
>> I KNEW BOTH.
RYAN WORKED FOR ME FOR A
YEAR-AND-A-HALF.
HE WAS A BUSSER.
>> HE WAS?
OKAY.
>> ADAM WAS NEVER A SOCIAL
PERSON.
HE USED TO COME IN AND KEEP HIS
HEAD DOWN AND NEVER SURE OF
HIMSELF.
>> YOU KNEW THERE WAS SOMETHING?
>> SHE TOLD US THAT HE HAD THE
CONDITION THERE, ASBERGER'S AND
ALWAYS HAD AN ISSUE IN SCHOOL
SOCIALLY BECAUSE HE WAS A VERY
HIGHLY INTELLIGENT KID AND HIGH
I.Q. AND GRADUATED AROUND TENTH
GRADE OR SO.
>> GRADUATED EARLY.
>> YEAH, LIKE TENTH GRADE, YEAH,
VERY, VERY INTELLIGENT KID, AND
I MENTIONED EARLIER, TOO, A LOT
OF PEOPLE ARE MENTIONING
ASBERGER'S AND I WOULD LIKE TO
SAY SOMETHING ABOUT THAT.
I THINK THAT A LOT OF KIDS HAVE
IT, AND I DON'T THINK IT HAS
ANYTHING TO DO WITH THE
SITUATION AT ALL BECAUSE KIDS
WITH THAT KNOW THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN RIGHT AND WRONG.
>> SHE TALKED, NANCY TALKED
THROUGH THE YEARS ABOUT HER SON.
>> SHE CAME IN HERE AND WE
SOCIALIZED AND WENT OUT AND
NEVER TALKED ABOUT THE FAMILY.
SHE WAS -- SHE JUST CAME IN TO
HAVE A GREAT TIME, TO TALK,
AND --
>> GET IT OFF HER MIND IF
ANYTHING.
>> SHE DID BUT SHE WOULD ONLY
SAY IT HAS BEEN HARD FOR HER,
YOU KNOW, IT WAS REALLY HARD FOR
HER, BRINGING HIM UP AND SHE WAS
ALWAYS --
>> SHE TALKED ABOUT THE
CHALLENGE OF IT.
>> YEAH, BUT ALWAYS ON IT.
SHE WAS JUST SAYING, YEAH, NEVER
REALLY DIDN'T HAVE TO COME IN
HERE AND TALK ABOUT IT AND
DIDN'T WANT TO TALK ABOUT IT.
SHE WOULD MENTION IT HAS BEEN
DIFFICULT AND SO MUCH FOR HIM TO
TRY TO GET HIM HELP HERE OR
THERE OR DOING DIFFERENT THINGS.
>> ONE OF THE THINGS WE HEARD A
LOT ABOUT IS SHE WAS PASSIONATE
ABOUT GUNS AND COLLECTED GUNS.
IS THAT SOMETHING YOU KNEW ABOUT
OR SURPRISED WHEN YOU HEAR?
>> I WOULD SAY IN THE LAST THREE
YEARS OR SO SHE PICKED UP THE
HOBBY.
I DON'T KNOW WHO GOT HER INTO
IT.
SHE REALLY ENJOYED IT, TARGET
SHOOTING, SO I DIDN'T KNOW.
I HAD NO IDEA.
>> NOT COLLECTING?
>> SHE WAS A TARGET SHOOTER.
SHE PROBABLY HAD SOME GUNS SHE
USED TO TAKE TO THE RANGE AND
PRACTICE WITH.
I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT SHE OWNED OR
WHAT SHE HAD.
SHE JUST SAID SHE ENJOYED IT AND
THAT WAS IT.
WE DON'T KNOW IF SHE TOOK HER
SONS, DIDN'T TAKE HER SONS, SHE
DIDN'T TALK ABOUT IT MUCH.
I TOOK THIS UP, IT IS FUN, THAT
KIND OF THING.
>> GIVEN THAT YOU KNEW HER AS A
PERSON, WOULD YOU -- DO YOU
THINK SHE IS THE KIND OF
APPROXIMATE EARN THAT WOULD HAVE
THE GUNS AROUND THE HOUSE?
WOULD THEY BE LOCKED UP?
>> THEY WOULD HAVE BEEN LOCKED
UP.
>> SHE IS FAR TOO BRIGHT FOR
THAT.
SHE WAS VERY SMART.
SHE UNDERSTOOD.
>> WHAT DO YOU THINK SOME OF THE
BIGGEST MISCONCEPTIONS ARE THAT
YOU HAVE HEARD ON THE NEWS?
>> I THINK MOSTLY BETWEEN THE
CONDITION HE HAD WHICH PEOPLE
COULD CONFUSE FOR BEING THE
REASON AND THE GUNS.
I MEAN, WE DON'T THINK IT HAS
ANYTHING TO DO WITH HER
CHARACTER.
>> DONATED HER TIME WITH ALL THE
CHARITABLE WORK AND HELPING
PEOPLE THAT NEEDED HELP AND
HELPING AIDS PEOPLE AND DONATING
MONEY AND FOR AIDS AND CHARITY
AND THAT'S WHAT SHE DID.
SHE DIDN'T GET PAID FOR DOING
WHAT SHE DID AND SHE DID ALL
CHARITABLE WORK AND ALL ON HER
OWN.
>> VERY GENEROUS.
>> VERY GENEROUS PERSON.
COULD BE SITTING HERE AND YOU
ARE TALKING TO HER AND THEY
WOULD BE SAYING I DON'T HAVE ANY
MONEY FOR THIS OR ANY MONEY FOR
THAT AND SHE WOULD TAKE HER
CHECKBOOK OUT AND WRITE A CHECK
AND GIVE IT TO THE PERSON
WITHOUT KNOWING THEM.
THAT'S THE KIND OF PERSON SHE
WAS.
>> ALL RIGHT.
I WANT TO BRING IN SUSAN
CANDIOTTI WITH THE LATEST ON THE
INVESTIGATION.
I KNOW WE WERE HEARING THOSE
FRIENDS OF NANCY LANZA TALKING
ABOUT HOW SHE PICKED UP THE
HOBBY OVER THE PAST THREE YEARS
AND THEY DON'T THINK SHE
WOULD -- THEY WERE VERY ADAMANT
SHE WOULDN'T BE THE PERSON THAT
WOULD LEAVE HER GUNS LOOSE.
SHE WOULD LOCK THEM UP WHAT ARE
YOU LEARNING ABOUT TARGET
SHOOTING, NANCY LANZA AND ADAM?
>> IT IS ONE OF THE THINGS
INVESTIGATORS HAVE TO LOOK AT.
WHAT WERE BOTH DOING, IN
PARTICULAR HER SON?
THEY'RE FINDING OUT MORE ABOUT
THAT.
THEY'RE LEARNING THAT IN FACT
BOTH MOTHER AND SON HAVE BEEN TO
TARGET PRACTICE AND DID GO TO
GUN RANGES AND SEVERAL TIMES
OVER THE PAST SEVERAL YEARS.
THEY DON'T KNOW EXACTLY HOW
OFTEN YET BUT MOST RECENTLY FOR
ADAM ANYWAY WAS IN THE LAST SIX
MONTHS, AND AGAIN OVER THE
COURSE OF SEVERAL YEARS.
THE REASON THEY DON'T KNOW THE
BIG PICTURE, THE FULL PICTURE
YET IS BECAUSE ATF IS STILL IN
THE PROCESS OF CANVASSING ALL OF
THE GUN RANGES IN THE AREA AND
THERE ARE A TON OF THEM IN
ADDITION TO LICENSED GUN DEALERS
TO TRY TO GET MORE INFORMATION
ABOUT THIS.
THEY'RE STILL FOLLOWING A LOT OF
LEADS, AND THEY'RE ALSO LOOKING
AT COMPUTERS, COMPUTERS THAT
THEY HAVE DISCOVERED IN THE
HOME, A COUPLE OF THEM WE HAVE
LEARNED FROM OUR LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS IS THAT THEY WERE
SMASHED, SMASHED TO SMITHEREENS.
>> TRYING TO DESTROY EVIDENCE.
>> IT WOULD APPEAR TO BE THE
CASE.
THAT'S THE APPARENT INDICATION.
NOW THEY HAVE TO PICK UP THE
PIECES LITERALLY AND TRY TO PULL
THINGS TOGETHER AND EXAMINE THE
HARD DRIVE WHAT WILL THEY LOOK
FOR?
THEY WILL BE CHECKING TO SEE IF
HE SENT E-MAILS TO ANYONE, WHAT
WEBSITES DID HE VISIT, WAS IN
CHAT ROOMS, MESSAGE BOARDS, ANY
INDICATION AS TO A POSSIBLE
MOTIVE IN ALL OF THIS.
WHO DID HE COMMUNICATE WITH IF
ANYONE?
THOSE ARE THE KINDS OF THINGS
THEY'RE LOOKING AT, AND REMEMBER
THEY ARE ALSO DOING A COMPLETE
HISTORY OF ALL OF THE WEAPONS
THAT WERE USED IN THIS TERRIBLE
TRAGEDY.
WE HAVE GOT THE ONE MADE BY
BUSHMASTER WHICH WAS THE ASSAULT
TYPE RIFLE, AND WE KNOW THAT HE
CAME ACCORDING TO OFFICIALS WITH
A TON OF AMMUNITION.
HE WAS ARMED TO THE HILT WHEN HE
WENT TO THAT SCHOOL, MULTIPLE
MAGAZINES.
>> HUNDREDS BULLETS.
>> EXTRA BULLETS ON TOP OF THAT,
30 ROUND MAGAZINES, A LOT TO GO
OVER, SO THEY'LL BE LOOKING AT
ALL OF THAT.
WE WERE ALSO THERE YESTERDAY
WHEN WE SAW HIS CAR BEING TOWED
AWAY.
THEY'RE GOING TO BE GOING OVER
THAT VEHICLE FROM TOP TO BOTTOM
INSIDE THE TRUNK, YOU WILL
REMEMBER, WAS AN EXTRA RIFLE.
>> I KNOW WE DON'T KNOW ABOUT
MOTIVE AND WHEN THEY GET THIS
INFORMATION THEY'LL GET MORE AND
MORE INFORMATION.
WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT HIM
PLAYING VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES?
>> WE DON'T KNOW MUCH ABOUT THAT
YET.
THAT'S ONE THING OF COURSE
THEY'LL BE LOOKING FOR, ANY
INDICATION OF THAT, WHAT GAMES
MAY HAVE BEEN DOWNLOADED ON THE
COMPUTER AND HOWEVER TODAY I
SPOKE WITH A FRIEND OF HIS, I
GUESS YOU CALL A FRIEND OF HIS
THAT WENT TO HIGH SCHOOL WITH
HIM AND HE SAID IN THEIR
COMPUTER CLASS AND TECH CLASS
THEY WOULD PLAY A COUPLE OF
GAMES, ONE CALLED STARCRAFT AND
WARCRAFT THAT INVOLVES SHOOTING
UP ENEMIES AND THIS KIND OF
THING.
>> KILLING AND AWFUL THINGS.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH, SUSAN.
WE APPRECIATE IT.
WHAT WE KNOW AND WHAT AT THIS
POINT WE DON'T KNOW.
UP FRONT NEXT, THE WOMAN THAT
WROTE THE BACKLOG I AM ADAM
LANZA'S MOTHER, THE TITLE OF IT.
IT CALLED ATTENTION TO THE
CHALLENGE OF RAISING A CHILD
WITH VERY SERIOUS MENTAL
ILLNESS.
WHAT SHE GOT IN RESPONSE IS A
FIRE STORM.
SHE RESPONDS TO THE CONTROVERSY
AND THE CRITICISM NEXT AND LATER
THE PRINCIPAL HERO, REMEMBERED
BY THE PEOPLE WHO KNEW HER.
YOU KNOW
THAT LITTLE 50-POUND THINGY
AT THE DOCTOR'S OFFICE
WHEN THEY WEIGH YOU,
AND THEY HAVE TO MOVE IT OVER?
MY DOCTOR DOES NOT
HAVE TO DO THAT ANYMORE.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR EVERY 2 POUNDS YOU LOSE
THROUGH DIET AND EXERCISE
ALLI CAN HELP YOU LOSE
ONE MORE
BY BLOCKING SOME OF THE FAT
YOU EAT.
FEELS GREAT.
SIMPLE. EFFECTIVE.
TAKE THAT, 50 POUND THINGY.
LET'S FIGHT FAT WITH ALLI.
HAVE A HEALTHIER HOLIDAY
AT LETSFIGHTHOLIDAYFAT.COM.
♪
First rule of taking the
world by surprise?
Do something the world
will actually notice.
Introducing the entirely
new Ford Fusion.
With a turbo-charged EcoBoost
engines and a hybrid that
doubles the fuel economy of
the average vehicle.
It's an entirely new idea of
what a car can be.
UP HIGH!
OK. DON'T YOU HAVE
ANY USEFULL APPS ON THAT THING?
WHO DO YOU THINK I AM,
Quicken Loans?
♪
AT Quicken Loans,
OUR AMAZINGLY USEFUL
MORTGAGE CALCULATOR APP
ALLOWS YOU TO QUICKLY CALCULATE
YOUR MORTGAGE PAYMENT
BASED ON TODAY'S INCREDIBLY LOW
INTEREST RATES...
RIGHT FROM YOUR IPHONE
OR ANDROID SMARTPHONE.
ONE MORE WAY Quicken Loans
IS ENGINEERED TO AMAZE.
♪
>>> I AM ADAM LANZA'S MOTHER,
AND IT WENT VIRAL, ABOUT
LITERALLY THE INSTANT AFTER IT
WAS PUBLISHED.
LIZA LONG WROTE VIVIDLY ABOUT
HER 13-YEAR-OLD SON MICHAEL.
SHE CHANGED HIS NAME, SHE SAYS,
TO PROTECT HIS PRIVACY.
HERE IS WHAT SHE WROTE.
I LIVE WITH A SON WHO IS
MENTALLY ILL.
I LOVE MY SON.
HE TERRIFIES ME.
A FEW WEEKS AGO MICHAEL PULLED A
KNIFE AND THREATENED TO KILL ME
AND THEN HIMSELF AFTER I ASKED
HIM TO RETURN HIS OVERDUE
LIBRARY BOOKS.
NOW, THIS BLOG WAS VERY RAW AND
EMOTIONAL AND RAISED QUESTIONS
ABOUT PARENTING A CHILD WITH
MENTAL ILLNESS.
ALSO, THERE WERE A LOT OF
CRITICS, PEOPLE WONDERING WHY
LIZA LONG WOULD CHOOSE TO BE SO
PUBLIC ABOUT HER SON MICHAEL.
I SPOKE TO HER EARLIER AND ASKED
HER WHY SHE WROTE THE BLOG.
>> YOU KNOW, THIS BLOG WAS A
REALLY PERSONAL AND VISCERAL
RESPONSE TO THE ABSOLUTELY
TRAGIC SHOOTINGS THAT OCCURRED
IN CONNECTICUT ON FRIDAY AND
WHEN I HEARD ABOUT THE
SHOOTINGS, I CLOSED MY OFFICE
DOOR AND JUST STARTED TO SHAKE
AND LATER THAT EVENING AS I SAT
DOWN, I CONFRONTED A LOT OF MY
OWN FEARS AND THE THOUGHT
PROCESS I WAS GOING THROUGH
THROUGH THE COURSE OF THE WEEK
AND THAT BLOG POST WAS A RESULT
OF THAT REALLY HARD LOOK AT MY
OWN LIFE AND MY OWN
CIRCUMSTANCES.
>> LIZA, YOU WRITE ABOUT -- I
WILL USE YOUR WORDS.
I KNOW THIS IS HARD TO SAY.
YOU WRITE ABOUT YOUR CHILD
THREATENING YOU WITH A KNIFE.
THIS WAS NORMAL BEHAVIOR FOR
HIM?
>> THIS IS A SCARY THING, ERIN.
THE EXTENT TO WHICH WE HAD
NORMALIZED THAT BEHAVIOR, WHAT I
TRIED TO DESCRIBE MICHAEL TO
PEOPLE, ANYONE THAT KNOWS HIM
KNOWS THAT 97% OF THE TIME HE IS
JUST THE SWEETEST, BRIGHTEST,
KINDEST MOST ARTICULATE CHILD,
BUT SOMETIMES FOR NO APPARENT
REASON HE WILL JUST TURN INTO
THIS ABSOLUTE RAGING -- I DON'T
KNOW HOW TO DESCRIBE IT.
YOU HAVE TO SEE IT TO BELIEVE
IT.
I STOPPED AND SAID TO MYSELF
THIS ISN'T NORMAL.
I HAVE TO FACE UP TO THE FACT
THAT I HAVE A SICK SON, AND WE
NEED HELP, AND, ERIN, THAT'S
REALLY WHAT THE BLOG POST WAS
ABOUT.
IT WAS ABOUT A CRY FOR HELP IN A
SITUATION WHERE I WAS FEELING
VERY HELPLESS.
>> DO YOU KNOW WHAT HE HAS?
WHAT CAUSES HIM TO DO THIS?
HAS IT EVER BEEN DIAGNOSED?
>> WE HAVE HAD VARIETY OF
DIAGNOSES.
WE HAVE LOOKED AT INTERMITTENT
EXPLOSIVE DISORDER, OPPOSITIONAL
DEFIANT DISORDER, AUTISM
SPECTRUM DISORDER ALTHOUGH THERE
IS DISAGREEMENT ON THAT AND ALSO
FINALLY ADHD.
>> SO IT IS STILL SORT OF YOU'RE
NOT REALLY SURE.
I KNOW THAT TO GIVE OUR VIEWERS
BACKGROUND HERE, THAT YOU AND
YOUR HUSBAND, HE HAS ACTUALLY
BEEN INTO JUVENILE DETENTION
FOUR TIMES AND NOW AT WHAT YOU
CALL AN ACUTE INPATIENT
FACILITY, A MENTAL HEALTH
INSTITUTION, AND YOU ACTUALLY
TOOK HIM THERE AFTER THE KNIFE
INCIDENT.
AGAIN, I WANT TO QUOTE LIZA FOR
THE VIEWERS THAT DON'T KNOW THE
BLOG WHEN YOU WRITE ABOUT THAT
MOMENT YOU WROTE HE WAS IN A
FULL BLOWN HIT SCREAMING AND
HITTING.
I HUGGED HIM CLOSE SO HE
COULDN'T ESCAPE FROM THE CAR.
HE BIT ME SEVERAL TIMES AND
REPEATEDLY JABBED HIS ELBOWS
INTO MY RIB CAGE.
I AM STILL STRONGER THAN HE IS
BUT I WON'T BE FOR MUCH LONGER.
HOW LONG WILL HE BE IN THAT
INSTITUTION AND WHAT WILL YOU DO
WHEN HE COMES HOME?
>> ERIN, THAT'S THE REASON I
WROTE THE BLOG.
PEOPLE HAVE HAD A HARD TIME
UNDERSTANDING THIS, BUT WHERE WE
LIVE I DON'T KNOW HOW IT IS
WHERE YOU LIVE BUT WHERE WE LIVE
MENTAL HEALTH TREATMENT IS
PRETTY SHORT-TERM, AND SO THIS
FACILITY FOR YOUNG ADULTS, 10 TO
14 DAYS MAYBE AT THE MOST, MAYBE
EVEN LESS, AND AFTER THAT THERE
AREN'T A LOT OF GOOD OPTIONS FOR
CONTINUED RESIDENTIAL TREATMENT
HERE.
THAT'S THE BIGGEST CHALLENGE
THAT I AM FACING, THE ADVICE I
GOT WAS I NEEDED TO PRESS
CHARGES SO THAT WE COULD CREATE
A PAPER TRAIL AGAIN AND HE DID
GET EXCELLENT FOLLOW THROUGH
CARE WHEN HE HAD TO DO JUVENILE
DETENTION AS A YOUNGER BOY, BUT
I JUST DON'T FEEL LIKE JAIL IS
THE RIGHT PLACE FOR MY SON, AND
I AM JUST REALLY HOPING THAT WE
CAN FIND ANOTHER SOLUTION FOR
HIM.
>> YOU HAVE BEEN CRITICIZED FOR
WRITING THIS BLOG AND I KNOW
YOU'RE WELL AWARE THAT FAR AND
YOU WROTE IT UNDER YOUR OWN NAME
SO PEOPLE COULD FIGURE OUT WHO
YOUR SON IS AND I KNOW MICHAEL
ISN'T HIS REAL NAME AND ANYONE
THAT KNEW YOU COULD FIGURE IT
OUT.
YOU HAVE BEEN CRITICIZED FOR
DOING THAT.
MAYBE IF HE DOES GROW UP AND GET
THROUGH THIS AND IS ABLE TO
BECOME A FUNCTIONING MEMBER OF
SOCIETY THAT THIS WOULD DOG HIM
FOR THE REST OF HIS LIFE AND
YOUR WORDS WOULD BE THERE.
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THAT?
>> THOSE KINDS OF CRITICISMS
WILL COME UP ANY TIME THERE IS A
SITUATION LIKE THIS.
FIRST AND FOREMOST, I REALIZE
THIS SOUNDS HOPELESSLY NAIVE
NOW.
DID I BELIEVE THAT MY BLOG WAS
ANONYMOUS, AND IF YOU LOOK AT
THE THE SOCCER MOM MY NAME IS
NOT ON THERE.
WHERE THE LINK CAME IS WITH IS
WHEN I PUBLISHED ON THE BLUE
REVIEW, AND THAT WAS LINKED TO
MY BLOG.
THAT, YOU KNOW, HONESTLY, AS YOU
PROBABLY KNOW, THERE IS A GREAT
WOMAN NAMED SARA OUT THERE WHO
HAS A WONDERFUL BLOG, VERY
ARTICULATE AND PASSIONATE AND
VERY CONCERNED ABOUT CHILDREN'S
PRIVACY ISSUES.
FRANKLY, ERIN, I THINK THEY ARE
CONCERNS ARE LEGITIMATE AND
CONCERNS ABOUT CHILDREN'S
PRIVACY ISSUES ARE LEGITIMATE.
MY SON DOES KNOW ABOUT THIS
PIECE.
HIS TAKE ON IT WAS, MOM, IF WE
CAN HELP PEOPLE TO UNDERSTAND,
THEN THIS IS A GOOD THING.
>> LIZA, LET ME ASK YOU, YOU
MENTIONED SARA, AND OF COURSE
WHO YOU'RE REFERRING TO, SHE WAS
ANOTHER MOM, INCREDIBLY
SUPPORTIVE OF YOU AND YOU PUT
OUT A JOINT STATEMENT SAYING
LET'S HAVE A CONVERSATION ABOUT
MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES.
WHEN SHE POSTED ONLINE SOME OF
YOUR PRIOR BLOGS, I READ THEM.
YOU WROTE THINGS ABOUT YOUR
SON'S BEHAVIOR.
IT MAKES WANT TO THROTTLE YOU
AND I QUIT, LET THE STATE TAKE
CARE OF YOU AND ANOTHER TIME MY
DAY DREAMS INVOLVE MY DEATH OR
FEDERAL PRISON.
ARE THOSE THE RAW EMOTIONS YOU
FEEL AS A MOTHER AND MOST PEOPLE
DON'T SAY OR WERE YOU
EXAGGERATING OR TELL ME HOW THAT
HAPPENED.
>> WELL, I MEAN, FIRST OF ALL, I
HAVE TO ADMIT YOU GUYS HAVE ALL
SCRUTINIZED MY BLOG A WHOLE LOT
MORE THAN I EVER THOUGHT IT
WOULD BE SCRUTINIZED.
I DON'T THINK ANYONE IN AMERICA
THINKS ANYONE READS THEIR BLOGS,
SO, YEAH, I THINK ONE OF THE
HALLMARKS OF MY WRITING AND ONE
OF THE REASONS THIS LAST PIECE
CONNECTED WITH SO MANY PEOPLE IS
I DO HAVE A TENDENCY TO JUST
KIND OF SAY WHAT IS ON MY MIND,
AND I WROTE THOSE WORDS AND
THOSE ARE MY WORDS.
I AM NOT DISOWNING THEM.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT A FOUR-YEAR --
THAT'S A FOUR-YEAR SLICE OF
HISTORY.
>> LET ME ASK YOU A QUESTION.
DO YOU OWN A GUN?
>> HEAVEN'S NO, NO, NO, NO.
>> BECAUSE OBVIOUSLY YOU'RE
WRITING ABOUT MENTAL HEALTH HERE
AND SOME PEOPLE HAVE SAID YOU
HAVE FAIR POINTS, BUT YOU KNOW
DON'T LET THIS OBSCURE THE
NATIONAL DEBATE WE NEED TO HAVE
ABOUT GUN CONTROL AND WHAT WE
NEED TO DO.
>> OH, MY GOODNESS, NO.
I HAVE CAUGHT THAT FROM MORE
THAN ONE PERSON AND I THINK THAT
THE LINE IN QUESTION IS
SOMETHING ABOUT IT IS EASY TO
TALK ABOUT GUN CONTROL AND IT IS
TIME TO TALK ABOUT MENTAL HEALTH
AND IF I CAN CLARIFY WHAT I MEAN
BY EASY, IT IS THAT WE CAN FRAME
THE GUN CONTROL DEBATE IN TERMS
OF WRITE AND WRONG.
IT IS RIGHT TO HAVE GUN CONTROL
OR IT IS WRONG IF SOME PEOPLE
WOULD SAY TO HAVE GUN CONTROL,
SO THAT'S A SIMPLE WAY TO DEBATE
A QUESTION.
I DON'T THINK YOU CAN SAY THAT
MENTAL HEALTH IS RIGHT OR WRONG.
>> YES.
ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH, LIZA.
APPRECIATE YOUR TAKING THE TIME
AND COMING AND TALKING ABOUT IN.
>> THANK YOU, ERIN.
I REALLY APPRECIATE YOU
HIGHLIGHTING THIS IMPORTANT
ISSUE OF MENTAL HEALTH AND I
JUST REALLY FEEL LIKE THIS IS A
CONVERSATION THAT WE NEED TO
HAVE AS A NATION THAT WE NEED TO
DO SOMETHING FOR OUR CHILDREN
AND ADULTS WHO STRUGGLE WITH
BEHAVIORAL AND MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES.
>> WE CERTAINLY DO.
THANKS.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> I ASKED LIZA WHY SHE PUT A
PICTURE UP OF HER SON ON HER
BLOG SINCE SHE CHANGED HIS NAME
AND WANTED TO PROTECT HIS
PRIVACY AND SHE WAS VERY OPEN.
THE PICTURE IS AGE 7 AND HE
LOOKS NOTHING LIKE THAT.
I WANT TO BRING IN DR. SANJAY
GUPTA.
SANJAY, WHEN YOU HEAR THIS
STORY, AND YOU SEE LIZA TALKING
ABOUT HER CHILD AND HER
STRUGGLES, SHE HAS TAKEN A LOT
OF CRITICISM FOR THAT FROM A LOT
OF PEOPLE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
>> IT WAS A REALLY GOOD
INTERVIEW.
IT WAS INTERESTING.
YOU ALMOST GOT THE SENSE IT WAS
A LITTLE THERAPEUTIC FOR HER,
HER WRITING, SHE WRITES THIS
STUFF AND NOW SEEING HER AND
MEETING HER THROUGH THAT
INTERVIEW, YOU CAN TELL SHE IS
NOT THE KIND OF MOM TO DO THESE
THINGS BUT SHE IS FRUSTRATED.
THE MENTAL HEALTH ISSUE, IMAGINE
THIS, THE THRESHOLD TO GET YOUR
CHILD TREATMENT IS THAT THEY
HAVE TO BE OF IMMINENT HARM TO
THEMSELVES OR OTHER PEOPLE.
IT IS LIKE SAYING YOU CAN ONLY
GO TO THE HOSPITAL IF YOU'RE
ALREADY HAVING A HEART ATTACK.
IT DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE.
THIS IS THE PROBLEM WHEN YOU
TALK ABOUT PUTTING MENTAL HEALTH
ON PAR WITH PHYSICAL HEALTH.
IT IS NOT RIGHT NOW.
>> IT IS HARD WHEN SHE SAID YOU
ARE PUT IN A POSITION YOU HAVE
TO CHARGE YOUR OWN CHILD WITH
BATTERY OR ASSAULT.
HER HUSBAND HAD TO DO THAT IN
ORDER TO GET HIM INTO JUVENILE
CARE.
HAVE YOU DONE THE NUMBERS.
1 IN 5 CHILDREN HAVE A MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUE IN THIS COUNTRY.
THAT'S AN AMAZING NUMBER.
>> IT IS AN AMAZING NUMBER AND
THE MENTAL HEALTH RESOURCES ARE
NOT THERE.
WHEN YOU PRESCRIBE A MEDICATION
OR TAKE SOMEONE OFF A
MEDICATION, ALL THE LITERATURE
SAYS YOU HAVE TO MONITOR THE
PERSON FOR A PERIOD OF TIME AND
THAT'S A VERY VULNERABLE TIME
PERIOD.
YOU KNOW AS WELL AS I DO THAT
THEY GET PRESCRIPTIONS AND DON'T
GET THE FOLLOW-UP AND THAT'S A
REAL PROBLEM AND SOMETHING THAT
IT COMES UP EVEN WITH REGARD TO
THE SITUATION AND TRAGEDY HERE.
>> AND ALSO SEEMS A LOT OF
PARENTS WOULD BE UNDERSTANDABLY
IN DENIAL, RIGHT?
MY CHILD DOESN'T HAVE A PROBLEM
OR THEY'RE GOING TO GROW OUT OF
IT OR NOBODY WANTS TO BE IN THAT
POSITION.
>> YEAH.
I THINK DENIAL IS A BIG PART OF
THIS.
I HAVE BEEN TALKING TO A LOT OF
PEOPLE AND WHAT I AM HEARING
MORE THAN ANYTHING ELSE IS THEY
ANGUISH OVER WHAT'S HAPPENING
WITH THEIR CHILDREN AND LOVE TO
GET THEIR CHILDREN TREATMENT AND
IT MEANS GIVING THEM A CRIMINAL
RECORD OR SOMEHOW SAYING THEY'RE
GOING TO HARM PEOPLE AND THEY
DON'T WANT TO TOO THAT.
THAT'S A TOUGH CHOICE FOR ANY
PARENT TO MAKE.
>> AND AS LIZA SAID, YOU COULD
SEE THE ANGUISH.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> SANJAY, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
>> UP NEXT WE'LL BRING YOU SOME
OF OUR OTHER TOP STORIES OF THE
DAY.
WE HAVE MORE HERE FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT INCLUDING THE STORY
OF A MAN WHO FOUND CHILDREN ON
HIS FRONT LAWN VICTIMS OF A
HORRIBLE CRIME AND THE WORLD AT
THAT MOMENT KNEW NOTHING ABOUT.
r
new Light Chicken Pot Pie Soup
and it's so rich
and creamy...
is it really 100 calories?
Let me put you on webcan...
...lean roasted chicken...
and a creamy broth
Mmm
I can still see you.
[ Male announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
EXECUTOR OF EFFICIENCY.
YOU CAN SPOT AN AMATEUR
FROM A MILE AWAY...
WHILE GOING SHOELESS
AND METAL-FREE IN SECONDS.
AND YOU...RENT FROM National.
BECAUSE ONLY National
LETS YOU CHOOSE ANY CAR
IN THE AISLE...AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE A FULL-SIZE
OR ABOVE,
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
NOW THIS...WILL WORK.
[ Male Announcer ]
JUST LIKE YOU, BUSINESS PRO.
JUST LIKE YOU.
GO National.
GO LIKE A PRO.
>>> WELCOME BACK.
TONIGHT WE START THE SECOND HALF
OF THE SHOW WITH OTHER KEY
STORIES WE'RE WATCHING TONIGHT
AND WE BEGIN WITH DEMOCRAT
DANIEL, THE MOST SENIOR OLDER
MEMBER DIED TODAY, REPRESENTING
HAWAII IN THE SENATE FOR FIVE
DECADES AND SECOND LONGEST
SERVING IN HISTORY.
HE WAS A MEDAL OF HONOR
RECIPIENT AND HOSPITALIZED LAST
WEEK BUT EVENTUALLY SUCCUMBED TO
RESPIRATORY COMPLICATIONS.
WE'RE TOLD HIS LAST WORD WAS
ALOHA.
INOUYE WAS 88 YEARS OLD.
>>> FISCAL CLIFF TALKS MAY BE
GAINING MOMENTUM.
PRESIDENT OBAMA MET WITH JOHN
BOEHNER AFTER BOEHNER INDICATED
HE WAS WILLING TO MAKE NEW
CONCESSIONS.
IT WAS A FACE-TO-FACE MEETING,
THEIR THIRD IN EIGHT DAYS.
IT IS IMPORTANT AND A GOOD
THING.
IT LASTED 45 MINUTES.
IT HAS BEEN 501 DAYS SINCE THE
UNITED STATES LOST ITS TOP
CREDIT RATING.
>>> ELSEWHERE IN POLITICS A BIG
DECISION IN SOUTH CAROLINA.
GOVERNOR NIKKI HALEY APPOINTED
TIM SCOTT TO REPLACE OUT GOING
SENATOR JIM DEMITT.
HE WILL NOT ONLY BLACK MEMBER
AND WILL ONLY FILL THE SEAT
UNTIL A SPECIAL ELECTION IS HELD
IN NOVEMBER 2014.
THOSE RESULTS WILL DETERMINE WHO
FILLS THE REMAINING TWO YEARS OF
THE TERM.
YOU MAY RECALL EARLIER THIS
MONTH HE SAID HE WAS RESIGNING
BY JANUARY 1st TO LEAD A
CONSERVATIVE THINK TANK WHERE HE
SAID HE COULD MAKE A BIGGER
DIFFERENCE THAN HE DOES IN THE
SENATE.
AN INDEPENDENT REVIEW OF HOW THE
STATE DEPARTMENT HANDLED THE
ATTACK ON THE CONSULATE IN
BENGHAZI HAS BEEN SUBMITTED TO
HILLARY CLINTON AND IT WILL BE
SENT TO MEMBERS OF CONGRESS
BEFORE THEY ATTEND A CLOSED DOOR
BRIEFING WEDNESDAY.
THEY'LL BE BRIEFED BY THE
CONSISTENT REVIEW BOARD MEMBER
THAT IS CONDUCTED THE REVIEW.
EARLIER TODAY NEWTOWN BEGAN THE
UNBEARABLE TASK OF SAYING GOOD
BUY TO TWO OF FRIDAY'S YOUNGEST
VICTIMS.
AS WE WERE COMING INTO NEWTOWN
FROM A DISTANCE WE SAW A
GRAVEYARD AND A FUNERAL AND YOU
CHOKE UP AND TEAR UP JUST SEEING
THAT.
BRINGS HOME THE MAGNITUDE OF
WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
6-YEAR-OLD JACK PINTO AND NOAH
POZNER WERE BOTH LAID TO REST
TODAY.
WE HEAR NOAH WAS A VERY SMART
BOY AND LOVED READING AND
PLAYING WITH HIS SIBLINGS AND
CALLING HIS TWIN SISTER ARIELLE
HIS BEST FRIEND.
JACK PINTO WAS A HUGE FOOTBALL
FAN THAT LOVED THE NEW YORK
GIANTS.
HE LOVED THEM SO MUCH.
I KNOW HE LOVED, LOVED THE
GIANTS.
THAT WAS A REAL AREA OF PASSION
FOR THAT LITTLE BOY.
IT MUST HAVE BEEN HEARTBREAKING
TO BE THERE TODAY.
>> CERTAINLY BECAUSE IT JUST
DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
WE'RE WATCHING WHAT'S HAPPENING
TO THIS TOWN AND TO SEE ALL OF
THESE PEOPLE SHOW UP, THIS
LITTLE BOY'S FUNERAL, JUST A
6-YEAR-OLD BOY IN THE FIRST
GRADE AND THE PEOPLE YOU
NORMALLY SEE SHOW UP AT A
FUNERAL, THEY'RE OLDER.
THE PEOPLE THAT CAME TODAY,
CHILDREN, 5-YEAR-OLDS,
6-YEAR-OLDS, 7-YEAR-OLD CHILDREN
AND THEY ARRIVED WEARING LONG
SLEEVED SHIRTS AND SWEATSHIRTS
THAT HAD NEWTOWN WRESTLING ON IT
AND THE FAMILY HAD HAD ASKED FOR
PRIVACY.
WE TRIED TO GIVE THEM AS MUCH
PRIVACY AS POSSIBLE AND WHEN YOU
THINK ABOUT THE GLOBAL
SPOTLIGHT, THEY TRIED TO HAVE AS
MUCH ALONE TIME AS POSSIBLE AND
CERTAINLY THERE IS A LOT OF
INTEREST IN THIS LITTLE BOY WHO
LOVED SPORTS SO MUCH AND ONE
CHILD WHO SHOWED UP TO MOURN
TODAY WAS ACTUALLY WEARING A
MEDAL AND THE MEDAL IS
SIGNIFICANT BECAUSE I SPOKE TO A
MEMBER OF A WRESTLING TEAM IN A
NEARBY TOWN AND THIS TEAM SAYS
THAT JACK HAD JUST WON HIS FIRST
MEDAL THIS LAST WEEK, HIS VERY
FIRST MATCH, HE WON HIS FIRST
MEDAL.
AS YOU MENTIONED, HIS REAL LOVE
WAS FOOTBALL.
HE LOVED THE NEW YORK GIANTS.
HE LOVED VICTOR CRUZ, AND THAT
MESSAGE WENT ALL THE WAY TO
CRUZ.
HE TWEETED OUT THIS PICTURE.
HE TOOK A PICTURE OF HIS CLEATS
AND HIS GLOVES THAT HAD THE NAME
JACK PINTO ON IT.
HE SAID THIS GAME IS FOR YOU AND
AFTER LAST NIGHT'S GAME HERE IS
WHAT CRUZ TOLD REPORTERS.
>> IT WAS EMOTIONAL, MAN.
I WAS FIGHTING BACK TEARS TO DO
IT AND IT FELT GOOD.
IT FELT GOOD TO HONOR A FAMILY
GOING THROUGH SO MUCH.
JUST THE THOUGHT OF YOUR LITTLE
ONE OR YOUR CHILD OR SON OR
DAUGHTER GOING THROUGH SOMETHING
LIKE THAT, IT IS JUST
UNBELIEVABLE TO EVEN LISTEN TO
ON THE NEWS.
I PUT MY DAUGHTER INTO BED WITH
ME THAT NIGHT.
>> THE FAMILY REPORTEDLY WAS SO
MOVED AND KNEW HOW MUCH THAT THE
LITTLE BOY LOVED CRUZ THAT THEY
BURIED HIM IN A VICTOR CRUZ
JERSEY, THIS THE VERY FIRST OF
WHAT WILL BE MANY MORE DAYS OF
FUNERALS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN.
>> THANK YOU.
MORE HEROES OF THAT DAY.
ONE MAN SAW SIX SMALL CHILDREN
ON HIS FRONT LAWN, REFUGEE FROM
HORROR AND DIDN'T KNOW WHY AT
FIRST AND VICKI SOTO, A TEACHER
THAT GAVE EVERYTHING FOR HER
CHILDREN INCLUDING HER LIFE.
E B,
SWEET SILVER BELLS ♪
♪ ALL SEEM TO SAY
THROW CARE AWAY ♪
♪ FROM EVERYWHERE,
FILLING THE AIR ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
CHEX PARTY MIX.
EASY 15-MINUTE
HOMEMADE RECIPES
YOU JUST POP IN A MICROWAVE.
LIKE CARAMEL CHOCOLATE
DRIZZLES.
HAPPIER HOLIDAYS.
CHEX PARTY MIX.
PLAYS A KEY ROLE
THROUGHOUT OUR LIVES.
One A Day Men's 50+
IS A COMPLETE MULTIVITAMIN
DESIGNED FOR MEN'S HEALTH
CONCERNS AS WE AGE.
IT HAS 7 ANTIOXIDANTS
TO SUPPORT CELL HEALTH.
One A Day Men's 50+.
>>> JEAN ROSEN LIVES JUST DOWN
THE ROAD FROM THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND SO CLOSE
THAT FRIDAY MORNING BEFORE
ANYONE KNEW THE HORROR THAT HAD
HAPPENED, HE DISCOVERED SIX
TERRIFIED CHILDREN ON HIS FRONT
LAWN.
THEY TOLD HIM THEIR TEACHER HAD
JUST BEEN KILLED AND GENE IS OUT
FRONT WITH ME TONIGHT.
THANK YOU.
I KNOW IT IS HARD AND WITH ALL
OF THE MEDIA HERE TO COME AND
TALK ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED.
WHEN YOU SAW THOSE CHILDREN ON
YOUR YARD, DID YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
THAT SOMETHING WAS WRONG?
>> I HAD NO IDEA.
I THOUGHT THEY WERE DOING A SKIT
AND MAYBE THEY WERE CUB SCOUTS
OR GIRL SCOUTS AND PRACTICING
AND BECAUSE THEY WERE SITTING SO
NICELY AND THEN I SAW A MAN IN A
VERY AGITATED WAY SAYING IT IS
GOING TO BE ALL RIGHT, AND HE
KEPT RAISING HIS VOICE AND I
THOUGHT THAT WAS SO STRANGE, AND
I CAME TO THE CHILDREN AND THEY
WERE CRYING AND WAILING AND
MORTIFIED AND THERE WAS A SCHOOL
BUS DRIVER WITH THEM AND I
INVITED THEM INTO THE HOUSE, AND
SHE SAID THERE HAD BEEN AN
INCIDENT AT THE SCHOOL AND I HAD
NO IDEA WHAT IT WAS.
>> DID THE CHILDREN, HOW DID
THEY FIND THE WORDS TO TELL YOU?
THEY TOLD YOU, RIGHT?
>> THEY TOLD ME.
THEY JUST STARTED TALKING.
THE TWO BOYS MOSTLY TALKED, AND
THEY SAID WE CAN'T GO BACK TO
THAT SCHOOL, WE CAN'T GO BACK --
>> WE CAN'T GO BACK.
>> OUR TEACHER IS DEAD.
WHAT ARE WE GOING TO DO?
WE DON'T HAVE A TEACHER.
I COULD NOT TAKE THAT IN.
I COULD NOT ACCEPT THAT.
I JUST KEPT LISTENING TO THEM
AND THEN THEY TALKED MORE AND
THE BOY SAID, OH, NO, IT WAS A
BIG GUN AND A SMALL GUN AND THEN
I KNEW AND THEN THEY SAID THERE
WAS BLOOD, THERE WAS BLOOD, AND
THEN THEY SAID HER NAME, AND I
PRAYED THAT IT WASN'T THAT
TEACHER, AND IT WAS.
IT WAS THAT VERY PRETTY
27-YEAR-OLD TEACHER.
I DON'T KNOW HOW THEY FLED.
I THINK SHE MUST HAVE PROTECTED
THEM AND SAVED THEIR LIVES.
I DON'T KNOW IF THEY RAN ALL THE
WAY DOWN THE BOULEVARD, THE
STREET NEXT TO THE FIRE HOUSE.
I DON'T KNOW HOW THEY GOT TO MY
HOUSE.
THEY WERE SO BRAVE.
THEY WERE SO GOOD.
I BROUGHT DOWN SOME TOYS FROM MY
GRANDSON'S TOY CHEST AND I GAVE
THEM SOME JUICE AND WE CALLED
THEIR PARENTS.
THEY WERE VERY BRAVE.
VERY GOOD, AND I WAS AMAZED P I
WAS ASTOUNDED AT WHAT THEY WERE
TELLING ME.
>> THEY NOTICED EVERYTHING.
YOU ARE A PSYCHOLOGIST BY
TRAINING AND YOU TALK ABOUT
BEING A GRANDFATHER AND IT WAS A
GRANDFATHER THAT WAS YOU AT THAT
MOMENT.
>> THAT'S WHAT TRAINED ME, BEING
A GRANDFATHER.
I FELT LIKE I WAS WITH MY
GRANDCHILDREN, AND I FELT
PERFECTLY HAPPY WITH THEM.
THAT'S WHAT TRAINED ME, MY
GRANDDAUGHTER AND MY GRANDSON,
AND THEY WERE WITH ME, AND I
FELT COMFORTABLE.
THEY WERE VERY SWEET, AND THEY
CALMED DOWN A LITTLE AND THEY
WERE SO -- THEY KEPT REPEATING
THEY CAN'T GO BACK TO THE SCHOOL
BECAUSE THEY DON'T HAVE A
TEACHER.
>> AND THEY'RE GRIEVING IS GOING
TO BE HARD FOR ADULTS TO
UNDERSTAND.
IT WILL BE DIFFERENT.
IT MAY BE MORE INTENSE.
WHAT MESSAGE DO YOU HAVE FOR
THOSE CHILDREN THAT CAME ONTO
YOUR YARD?
>> I WANT TO BE REUNITED WITH
THEM.
I WANT TO SEE THOSE CHILDREN,
AND I WANT TO TELL THEM HOW GOOD
AND BRAVE AND STRONG THEY ARE
AND I WANT TO TELL THEIR PARENTS
THAT, AND I WANT TO TELL THEM
THAT I WANT TO BE THEIR FRIEND
AND I WANT TO READ TO THEM AND I
WANT TO GIVE THEM SOMETHING
SPECIAL FOR CHRISTMAS AND I WANT
TO BE THEIR FRIEND AND I WANT
THEM TO SEE ME IN LIGHT INSTEAD
OF DARKNESS AS I SAW THEM.
I WANT THEIR PARENTS -- I HOPE
THEY WILL CALL ME BECAUSE I WANT
TO SEE THOSE CHILDREN.
THEY WERE VERY GOOD CHILDREN,
AND THEN SOMETHING HAPPENED WITH
ONE OF THE BOYS OUT OF THIS
GRIEF AND THIS CARNAGE AND HE
STOPPED AND HE BECAME VERY
COMPOSED AND ALL OF A SUDDEN HE
STOPPED AND HE LOOKED AT ME AND
HE SAID JUST SAYING YOUR HOUSE
IS VERY SMALL.
I THOUGHT, WHAT A BRIGHT,
WONDERFUL BOY AND HE JUST
BROUGHT TO ALL OF US A RESPITE,
A RESPITE FROM ALL OF THIS
DARKNESS, AND YOU KNOW WHAT?
I WANT TO SEE THESE KIDS.
I HOPE THEIR PARENTS WILL CALL
ME.
I WANT TO PUT MY ARMS AROUND
THEM AND TELL THEM THAT I LOVE
THEM AND I WANT THE CHILDREN TO
BE THE BASIS FOR OUR SOLUTION.
THAT'S WHAT I WANT.
>> I HOPE THAT THEY ARE AND I
HOPE YOU WILL BE THAT WHEN THEY
REMEMBER THAT DAY, THE BEACON OF
LIGHT FOR THEM, TOO.
THANK YOU SO MUCH, GENE.
>> I SO APPRECIATE YOU LETTING
ME TELL MY STORY.
>> WE APPRECIATE YOU TELLING IT.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
"OUTFRONT" NEXT, HAS THE WORLD
CHANGED AND PERHAPS IN A WAY FOR
THIS COUNTRY FOR THE BETTER?
JOHN LOOKS AT HOW FINALLY THERE
MIGHT BE A REASONABLE
CONVERSATION IN THIS COUNTRY
ABOUT GUNS.
THE HERO PRINCIPAL FROM THE
POINT OF VIEW OF A FRIEND WHO
KNEW HER.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS SHELDON, WHOSE LONG DY
SETTING UP THE NEWS
STARTS WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND A CHOICE.
TAKE TYLENOL OR TAKE ALEVE,
THE #1 RECOMMENDED PAIN
RELIEVER BY ORTHOPEDIC DOCTORS.
JUST TWO ALEVE
CAN KEEP PAIN AWAY ALL DAY.
BACK TO THE NEWS.
JUST TWO ALEVE
CAN KEEP PAIN AWAY ALL DAY.
WITH TWO TIMES THE POINTS
ON DINING IN RESTAURANTS,?
YOU MAY FIND
YOURSELF ASKING
WHY NOT, A LOT.
CHASE SAPPHIRE PREFERRED.
THERE'S MORE TO ENJOY.
>>> IN THE AFTERMATH OF THE
NEWTOWN TRAGEDY THERE IS GROWING
DEMAND FOR TIGHTER CONTROLS ON
GUNS.
A POLL FOUND A BIG SHIFT, THE
NUMBER OF PEOPLE THAT SAY THEY
STRONGLY SUPPORT STRICTER GUN
CONTROL LAWS WENT UP BY FIVE
POINTS AND THE NUMBER STRONGER
OPPOSED WENT DOWN FIVE POINTS
AND AS I RECALL AFTER THE
SHOOTING IN AURORA, YOU DIDN'T
SEE SUCH A BIG SHIFT.
AFTER SOME MASS SHOOTINGS YOU
DO.
THIS TIME IT IS A BIGGER MOVE,
AND THE QUESTION IS WILL IT GAIN
EVEN MORE MOMENTUM AND WILL
WASHINGTON ACTUALLY DO ANYTHING
ABOUT IT?
JOHN AVALON IS LOOKING INTO
THAT.
I KNOW LAWMAKERS FROM BOTH SIDES
OF THE PARTY AND EVEN STAUNCH,
STAUNCH MEMBERS THAT ARE
STAUNCHLY BACKED BY THE NRA ARE
UNITED IN THEIR GRIEF AND SAY
THEY WANT CHANGE TO HAPPEN.
WILL IT?
>> ERIN, SOMETIMES IT TAKES A
TRAGEDY TO MAKE US CONFRONT
REALITY.
AND YOU ARE STARTING TO SEE
POLITICIANS ON BOTH SIDES OF THE
AISLE SAY MAYBE NOW IS NOT THE
TIME TO RELY ON IDEOLOGY OR
PARTISAN POLITICS BUT TAKE A
LONG LOOK ON THE LAWS AROUND
GUNS AND NOT INFRINGING ON THE
SECOND AMENDMENT BUT WHAT
REASONABLE RESTRICTIONS CAN BE
PUT IN PLACE.
IN THE LAST 24 HOURS TWO
SENATORS WITH NRA RATINGS OF A,
JOE MANCHIN AND MARK WARNER SAID
THIS EVENT CHANGED THEM AND
THEY'RE OPEN TO NEW SOLUTIONS.
LET'S TAKE A LISTEN TO WHAT
SENATOR MANCHIN TOLD CHRISTIANE
AMANPOUR.
>> WHO WOULD HAVE THOUGHT IN
AMERICA OR ANYWHERE IN THE WORLD
CHILDREN WOULD BE SLAUGHTERED?
IT CHANGED ME.
I DON'T KNOW OF ANYBODY THAT
GOES HUNTING WITH AN ASSAULT
RIFLE.
I DON'T KNOW PEOPLE THAT NEED
10, 20, 30-ROUND CLIPS.
>> I BELIEVE EVERY AMERICAN HAS
SECOND AMENDMENT RIGHTS AND THE
ABILITY TO HUNT IS PART OF OUR
CULTURE AND I HAVE HAD AN NRA
RATING OF AN A, BUT, YOU KNOW,
ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
>> ERIN, THAT'S THE BEGINNING OF
WHAT MAY BE A SIGNIFICANT SHIFT
IN EVOLUTION ON THIS ISSUE.
THE NATION HAD AN ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAND THAT EXPIRED IN
2004.
THAT'S ONE OF THE THINGS
SENATORS ARE TALKING ABOUT
LOOKING AT.
THE FACT THESE SENATORS ARE
SAYING THEY'RE OPEN TO THIS KIND
OF CONVERSATION IS REALLY
SIGNIFICANT.
>> ALL RIGHT, JOHN, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
>> AS THE RESIDENTS OF MOUNTAIN
MOURN THE LOSS OF FRIENDS AND
FAMILY, ONE OF THE THINGS THAT
HELPS KEEP THEM GOING IS
CELEBRATING THOSE BRAVE AMID THE
CHAOS.
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG WAS ONE OF THEM.
ALL THREE OF HER CHILDREN
ATTENDED SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
AND SHE BECAME FRIENDS WITH MANY
TEACHERS THERE INCLUDING DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG.
MIRANDA IS HERE TO REMEMBER.
I KNOW THAT YOU HAVE THREE
CHILDREN AND ONE OF YOUR
CHILDREN HAS FRIENDS THAT HAVE
LOST SIBLINGS.
>> YES.
>> LET ME ASK YOU ABOUT DAWN.
YOU KNEW HER WELL AND WORKED
WITH HER FOR A WHILE.
>> I WORKED WITH HER BECAUSE I
WAS VERY ACTIVE AS A MOM IN THE
SCHOOL AND MY YOUNGEST DAUGHTER
WHEN SHE WAS THERE DAWN WAS
THERE AT THE SAME TIME AND DAWN
WAS AN UNUSUAL PRINCIPAL.
SHE DIDN'T HAVE THAT FORMALITY
THAT A LOT OF ADMINISTRATORS
MIGHT HAVE.
SHE HAD A RADIANT SMILE AND SHE
WAS ALWAYS ABOUT FUN AND WARMTH
AND YOU KIND OF FELT LIKE YOU
COULD JUST GIVE HER A HUG AS
SOON AS YOU MET HER AND SHE HAD
A RARE QUALITY.
>> HOW DO YOU FEEL AND HOW DOES
THIS TOWN FEEL?
JUST BEING HERE, IT IS SUCH A
PICTURE PERFECT LITTLE TOWN.
IT IS SMALL AND FEELS LIKE
EVERYBODY WOULD KNOW EVERYBODY
ELSE.
>> UH-HUH.
>> YEAH.
WE ARE ALL CONNECTED HERE.
I FELT A LITTLE CONFLICTED
TONIGHT ABOUT COMING OUT.
I WANTED TO MAKE SURE IT WAS THE
RIGHT THING TO DO.
I FELT LIKE I COULD HAVE AN
OPPORTUNITY TO TALK A LITTLE BIT
ABOUT THE COLLECTIVE GRIEF THAT
WE'RE FEELING AS A COMMUNITY AND
WE FEEL NUMB.
WE'RE CARRYING OUR GRIEF AROUND
WITH US.
WE HAVE THE THOUGHTS OF THE
PARENTS WHO LOST THEIR CHILDREN
IN OUR MINDS ALL THE TIME.
IT IS HARD.
EVERYTHING STOPPED NOW.
IT IS HARD TO GET ON WITH YOUR
ROUTINE.
IT IS IMPOSSIBLE.
I HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE TO MAKE
COFFEE WITHOUT FORGETTING WHAT I
AM DOING HALFWAY THROUGH AND I
JUST WANT TO GET THE MESSAGE OUT
TO MY FRIENDS AND NEIGHBORS,
ESPECIALLY THE ONES GRIEVING THE
MOST WHO HAVE LOST LOVED ONES
THAT WE'RE IN THIS TOGETHER AND
THAT THERE IS SO MUCH GOOD IN
THE WORLD AND THAT WE'RE GOING
TO HOLD ONTO IT TOGETHER.
>> I KNOW YOU WERE TELLING A
PERSONAL STORY JUST ABOUT HOW IT
IS HARD TO SLEEP.
>> YEAH.
>> WHEN YOU DOZED OFF LAST NIGHT
AND WOKE UP, YOU HAD TO WAKE
YOUR HUSBAND UP TO SEE IF IT WAS
REAL.
>> I WOKE HIM UP AND SAID IS
THIS REALLY HAPPENING?
THAT'S A LINE THAT HAS BEEN
RUNNING THROUGH MY HEAD AND I
MENTIONED THAT TO FRIENDS OF
MINE AND CAN THEY ALL COULD
RELATE TO THAT.
IT IS HARD TO BELIEVE IT.
IT IS HARD TO BELIEVE WHEN
PRESIDENT OBAMA GAVE THE
BEAUTIFUL SPEECH LAST NIGHT AND
HE LISTED THE MASSACRES THAT
HAVE HAPPENED IN OUR COUNTRY AND
THE TRAGIC EVENTS AND AT THE END
OF IT CAME THE NAME OF OUR
LITTLE TOWN THAT NO ONE ELSE
USED TO -- I USED TO HAVE TO
EXPLAIN WHERE IT WAS, AND THAT
WAS SHOCKING.
>> YOU DON'T WANT IT TO BE THAT
WAY.
YOU DON'T WANT IT TO BE
COLUMBINE.
>> EXACTLY.
I DON'T WANT PEOPLE TO ASSOCIATE
THE NAME OF OUR TOWN WITH THIS
HORRIBLE TRAGEDY.
OUR TOWN IS MORE THAN THAT.
IT IS A REALLY SPECIAL PLACE
WHERE PARENTS ARE SO COMMITTED
TO THEIR CHILDREN'S EDUCATION
AND BRINGING THEM UP WELL AND MY
KIDS HAVE SUCH WONDERFUL
MEMORIES OF SANDY HOOK.
IT IS A HUGE PART OF THEIR
CHILDHOOD AND I HAVE WONDERFUL
MEMORIES THERE, AND I WANT THEM
TO BE ABLE TO CONTINUE TO HAVE
THOSE MEMORIES AND NOT THINK OF
IT AS A CRIME SCENE.
>> THIS IS A TOUGH QUESTION TO
ASK GIVEN MY ROLE.
THE MEDIA, WHEN I WALK AROUND
HERE, I SEE A LOT OF PEOPLE LIKE
ME AND WE'RE TRYING TO COVER THE
STORY AND I KNOW THAT WE'RE
MAKING IT HARD, TOO, IN SOME
WAYS FOR YOU.
>> THANK YOU FOR ASKING THAT,
ERIN.
I CAME DOWN A COUPLE OF DAYS
AGO.
I CAME DOWN TO THE CENTER OF
SANDY HOOK HERE WHEN THE MEDIA
WAS HERE, AND I KEPT BUMPING
INTO FRIENDS AND FRIENDS OF
FRIENDS AND WE WOULD HOLD EACH
OTHER AND EMBRACE EACH OTHER AND
COME CAN TOGETHER AND THAT FEELS
LIKE QUITE ALL RIGHT NOW AND
WHEN I CAME HERE TONIGHT, I
DIDN'T SEE ANYBODY I KNEW, AND
WE REALLY FEEL THAT THE NATION
FEELS OUR PAIN AND WANTS TO
REACH OUT AND WANTS TO BE HERE
WITH US, AND THAT MEANS A GREAT
DEAL.
ON THE OTHER HAND, IT IS HARD TO
NOT BE ABLE TO GET TO DRIVE
AROUND YOUR OWN TOWN WHEN REALLY
WHAT WE NEED IS TO BE TOGETHER.
>> MIRANDA, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
WE APPRECIATE YOU TAKING THE
TIME TO SHARE WITH US.
>> THANK YOU.
>> UP NEXT, A TOWN FOREVER
CHANGED.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a
Droid Incredible 4G LTE
by HTC for $49.99.
YOU CAN STAY IN
AND SHARE SOMETHING...
OR YOU CAN GET OUT THERE
AND ACTUALLY SHARE SOMETHING.
♪
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
ADVIL PM® OR TYLENOL PM.
THE ADVIL PM® GUY
IS SPENDING LESS TIME
LYING AWAKE
WITH ANNOYING ACHES AND PAINS
AND MORE TIME ASLEEP.
ADVIL PM®. THE DIFFERENCE
IS A BETTER NIGHT'S SLEEP.
>>> FINALLY TONIGHT, A NEW
NORMAL IN NEWTOWN.
THE LIBRARY, THE GENERAL STORE,
THE DINER THAT FILLS WITH KIDS
AFTER HIGH SCHOOL BASKETBALL
GAMES, THE HALLMARKS OF A
PICTURE PERFECT NEW ENGLAND
TOWN, NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
DONNA MOVED HER 15 YEARS AGO TO
RAISE HER THREE KIDS.
>> THIS IS A TOWN WHERE I NEVER
LOCKED MY DOORS.
I DIDN'T LOCK MY CAR DOORS, MY
HOUSE WAS OPEN, AND MY KIDS RAN
BACK AND FORTH TO EACH OTHER'S
HOUSES.
NEVER FELT UNSAFE.
>> IT WAS SAFE.
JUST ONE MURDER IN THE PAST
DECADE.
ON FRIDAY THAT CHANGED.
20 SCHOOL CHILDREN GUNNED DOWN
IN THEIR CLASSROOMS AND FOUR
TEACHERS, THEIR SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST AND THEIR PRINCIPAL
ALL GONE.
NEWS OF A SHOOTING IN THE TOWN
WAS MET WITH DISBELIEF.
>> ALL I COULD THINK IS MAYBE IT
WAS A HUNTING ACCIDENT BECAUSE
NOTHING LIKE THIS WOULD EVER
HAPPEN IN NEWTOWN.
>> JOHN O'LEARY COACHES YOUTH
BASKETBALL AND ONE OF THE YOUNG
VICTIMS PLAYED FOR HIS TEAM.
>> NEVER EXPECTED IT.
SHOCKED.
>> THAT SHOCK IS STILL EVIDENT
EVERYWHERE YOU LOOK.
26 CHRISTMAS TREES LINE THE CURB
ACROSS THE STREET FROM THE FIRE
HOUSE WHERE SOME OF THE CHILDREN
FLED THE GUN FIRE.
THIS MORNING MOVING VANS DROVE
PAST DOWN THE ROAD TO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY TO START THE PROCESS
OF RESETTLING THE STUDENTS AT A
NEW SCHOOL.