PEOPLE ARE GOING TO KNOW
TOMORROW.
THAT'S JUST THE WORLD WE LIVE IN
THROUGH SOCIAL MEDIA OBVIOUSLY,
JUST TALKING TO OTHER PEOPLE.
SO THERE'S GOING TO BE A LOT OF
TOUGH CONVERSATIONS, WOLF.
I THINK I HAVE HAD SOME OF THOSE
ALREADY WITH MY OWN KIDS.
I THINK IT'S ONE OF THESE THINGS
WHERE PEOPLE ARE GOING TO HAVE
TO HAVE THE CONVERSATION BE AS
TRANSPARENT AS POSSIBLE.
I THINK SOME OF THE IMPORTANT
TIPS ARE TO ALLOW -- FIRST OF
ALL, I ALWAYS SAY CHECK YOUR OWN
PULSE BEFORE YOU GO INTO A
MEDICAL SITUATION.
HERE YOU CHECK YOUR OWN
FEELINGS.
YOU WANT TO MAKE SURE YOU'RE NOT
OVER TALKING THE CHILD, BUT ALSO
MAKING SURE YOU LISTEN TO THEM
FIRST.
SEE WHAT THEY KNOW AND THEN
SLOWLY START TO FILL IN DETAILS.
BUT YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
THESE ARE THE CONVERSATIONS THAT
ARE HAPPENING FRANKLY ALL OVER
THE COUNTRY OVER THE NEXT COUPLE
DAYS.
>> AS WE SPEAK RIGHT NOW, THE
PRESIDENT IS STILL COMFORTING
PEOPLE, SOME OF THE FAMILY
MEMBERS WHO HAVE SUFFERED SO
MUCH.
I CAN ONLY IMAGINE HOW THOSE
CONVERSATIONS ARE GOING.
WHAT DOES EVEN THE PRESIDENT SAY
TO A MOTHER AND A FATHER WHO
LOST A 6-YEAR-OLD?
>> YEAH, I DON'T KNOW.
I CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT THOSE
CONVERSATIONS ARE LIKE.
I THINK SIMPLY BEING THERE,
SIMPLY SHOWING THE SUPPORT,
SIMPLY AGAIN HAVING PEOPLE COME
TOGETHER.
YOU KNOW, I THINK SUFFERING IN
SILENCE, SUFFERING IN ISOLATION,
YOU KNOW, DEALING WITH THIS
ANGUISH I THINK PROBABLY MAKES
IT THAT MUCH HARDER.
SO I THINK THAT HE CAN HELP
WITH.
>> LET ME RESET WHAT'S GOING ON
RIGHT NOW, AND I WANT TO WELCOME
OUR VIEWERS NOT ONLY HERE IN THE
UNITED STATES BUT AROUND THE
WORLD.
WE'RE STANDING BY FOR THE START
OF THIS PRAYER VIGIL, THIS
INTERFAITH PRAYER VIGIL THAT
WILL TAKE PLACE HERE AT THE
NEWTOWN HIGH SCHOOL.
YOU SEE THE FOLKS ARE GATHERING.
THEY'RE TRYING TO COMFORT EACH
OTHER.
WE'RE WATCHING WHAT'S GOING ON
AS THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES.
HE HAS ARRIVED HERE.
HE FLEW FROM THE WHITE HOUSE,
FROM ANDREWS AIR FORCE BASE
OUTSIDE OF THE WHITE HOUSE IN
SUBURBAN MARYLAND, FLEW TO
HARTFORD AND THEN DROVE.
THE WEATHER HERE IS NOT GOOD
RIGHT NOW, SO HE COULD NOT
CHOPPER -- COULD NOT COME OVER
BY MARINE ONE.
HAD TO DRIVE FROM HARTFORD, AN
HOUR, HOUR AND A HALF DRIVE FROM
HERE, AND WE'RE IN NEWTOWN
WATCHING WHAT'S GOING ON.
ALL OF THESE MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS
HAVE JUST SPRUNG UP.
YOU CAN'T -- YOU CAN VIRTUALLY
NOT EVEN DRIVE THROUGH THE SMALL
STREETS OF NEWTOWN RIGHT NOW
IT'S SO, CROSO CROWDED.
PEOPLE ARE BRINGING CANDLES,
FLOWERS, CANDLES, TEDDY BEARS,
LEGOS.
WE'RE GETTING READY FOR WHAT
WILL BE A VERY, VERY EMOTIONAL
MEMORIAL SERVICE.
I'M WOLF BLITZER REPORTING HERE
FROM NEWTOWN.
ANDERSON COOPER IS RIGHT DOWN
THE STREET.
HE'S NEAR THE HIGH SCHOOL.
HE'S JOINING US AS WELL.
ANDERSON?
>> YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT, WOLF.
I'M ACTUALLY RIGHT RIGHT OUTSIDE
THE HIGH SCHOOL.
YOU SEE THE INSIDE OF THE
AUDITORIUM THERE AND REALLY FULL
TO CAPACITY.
A LOT OF PEOPLE STILL OUTSIDE
LOOKING LIKE THEY'RE LETTING
SOME MORE PEOPLE IN.
I'M NOT SURE WHAT PART OF THE
HIGH SCHOOL THEY'LL BE IN.
THEY'LL PROBABLY HAVE SOME
OVERFLOW ROOMS AVAILABLE.
WE ALSO UNDERSTAND THE PRESIDENT
IS ALREADY INSIDE THE HIGH
SCHOOL, HAS BEEN MEETING WITH
THE FAMILIES OF THOSE WHO HAVE
LOST LOVED ONES AND TRYING TO
OFFER THEM SOME COMFORT AND
LISTEN AS MUCH AS TALK, I'M
SURE, IN CASES LIKE THIS.
OFTEN JUST LISTENING TO PARENTS
TALK ABOUT THEIR CHILD, ABOUT
WHAT THEIR CHILD WAS LIKE,
SHARING STORIES AND SHARING IN
THAT GRIEF.
OUR JESSICA YELLIN, OUR CHIEF
WHITE HOUSE CORRESPONDENT IS
ALSO HERE WITH ME.
DO WE KNOW WHAT THE PRESIDENT IS
GOING TO BE SAYING TONIGHT?
>> I'M TOLD THAT HE'LL TALK
ABOUT THE NATION'S OBLIGATIONS
TO OUR CHILDREN.
THEY'RE NOT GETTING MORE
SPECIFIC THAN THAT, BUT I THINK
THAT THAT MEANS BOTH AS
FAMILIES, AS PARENTS, AND, YOU
KNOW, PERSONALLY TO CONNECT WITH
YOUR LOVED ONES, AND PROBABLY
MAYBE A BROAD REFERENCE TO OUR
OBLIGATIONS TO TAKE ACTION.
AGAIN, WE DON'T KNOW WHAT THE
PRESIDENT REALLY MEANS BY THAT.
IS IT SOME SORT OF POLITICAL
ACTION.
BUT, YOU KNOW, IN THESE
SPEECHES, THE PRESIDENT IS VERY
GOOD, ANDERSON, ABOUT FINDING
MOMENTS OF HEROISM TO TALK ABOUT
RESILIENCE AND THE AMERICAN
SPIRIT AND MOMENTS THAT SORT OF
CONNECT US TO WHAT'S GOOD ABOUT
OUR SPIRIT.
AND SO THAT WE FIND SOMETHING
POSITIVE IN ALL OF THIS.
>> AND THERE ARE CERTAINLY MANY
MOMENTS THAT WE KNOW OF ALREADY
FROM WHAT HAPPENED IN THAT
SCHOOL ON THAT DAY, TEACHERS
LIKE VICTORIA SOTO WHO
ESSENTIALLY SEEMED TO HAVE
SACRIFICED HER LIFE IN ORDER TO
PROTECT HER STUDENTS, TELLING
THE GUNMAN THAT THE STUDENTS
WERE NOT IN THE CLASSROOM WHEN
SHE HAD HIDDEN THEM.
AND I HAVE TALKED TO TEACHERS
WHO WERE, YOU KNOW, LITERALLY --
THEY KNEW SOMETHING WAS GOING
ON, DIDN'T KNOW WHAT IT WAS, AND
THEY SAT THEIR KIDS DOWN, GOT
THEM IN THE CORNER AND READ TO
THEM ALL DURING THE SHOOTING AND
JUST TRYING TO KEEP THEIR KIDS
CALM AND KEEP THEM -- THEIR
MINDS DIVERTED UNTIL A S.W.A.T.
TEAM ARRIVED.
>> THAT'S WHY IT'S JUST SUCH A
CHILLING STORY, A CHILLING
EXPERIENCE, BECAUSE THESE WERE
YOUNG CHILDREN, AND I THINK
THAT'S WHAT THE PRESIDENT HAS AN
OBLIGATION AND HE KNOWS THE
CHALLENGE TO CONNECT WITH.
THE SENSE THIS WAS A COMMUNITY
THAT DID EVERYTHING RIGHT.
LOOK AT WHAT THE SCHOOL DID WITH
SECURITY THEY PUT IN PLACE, WITH
HOW DEVOTED THESE TEACHERS WERE.
I MEAN, TWO THREW THEMSELVES AT
THE GUNMAN TO BLOCK THEIR WAY
AND IT HAPPENED TO THEM, AND
IT'S AN INSTANCE WHERE YOU
HAVE -- IT'S SO SENSELESS.
THERE'S NO WAY TO EXPLAIN EVEN
WHEN THE POLICE UNCOVER THE
MOTIVE.
THERE'S NO WAY TO EXPLAIN WHY
THIS HAD TO HAPPEN.
>> AND PRESIDENT OBAMA SPEAKING
AS A FATHER TONIGHT AS MUCH AS
AS THE PRESIDENT, AS A FATHER
WHO NO DOUBT HAD TO EXPLAIN TO
HIS OWN CHILDREN WHAT HAPPENED.
>> IT'S SUCH A GOOD POINT, AND,
YOU KNOW, WHEN -- THE TIMES WE
SEE HIM GET EMOTIONAL, IT IS
WHEN HE'S TALKING ABOUT SASHA
AND MALIA, AND IT'S INTERESTING,
THE MOMENT HE CHOKED UP ON
FRIDAY WHEN HE WAS SPEAKING
ABOUT THIS TRAGEDY WAS WHEN HE
SAID, THESE BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN,
THESE BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN, THAT'S
WHEN HE STARTED TO CRY.
AND, YOU KNOW, I HAVE SAID IT
BEFORE, BUT THAT WAS THE MOST
EMOTIONAL I HAVE EVER SEEN HIM
IN PUBLIC, AND IT WAS A POWERFUL
MOMENT FOR THE NATION OF RELEASE
FOR THE WHOLE NATION AND A WAY
FOR EVERYBODY TO EXPRESS GRIEF.
HE WENT TO HIS OWN DAUGHTER'S
DANCE REHEARSAL TODAY.
I DON'T KNOW IF HE WAS PLANNING
TO ANYWAY, BUT, YOU KNOW, IT'S
SORT OF -- I WONDER IF HE JUST
WANTED TO SPEND TIME WITH HIS
KIDS.
>> DO WE KNOW IS THE FIRST LADY
WITH HIM?
>> SHE'S NOT.
HIS FAMILY IS HOME TONIGHT, BUT
HE DID GET TO SPEND SOME TIME
WITH THE GIRLS TODAY.
>> HE IS JUST ONE OF THE MANY
SPEAKERS WHO WILL BE TALKING
DURING THIS SERVICE.
WAS TO BEGIN AT 7:00 EAST COAST
TIME.
IT NOW SEEMS LIKE IT MAY BE
DELAYED SOMEWHAT.
WE'RE NOT SURE IF THAT'S BECAUSE
THE PRESIDENT IS CONTINUING TO
MEET WITH FAMILIES OR WHAT THE
REASON FOR THE DELAY IS, BUT
OBVIOUSLY WE WILL BRING YOU THE
SERVICE IN ITS ENTIRETY WHEN IT
BEGINS, AND YOU'RE SEEING THE
INSIDE OF THE AUDITORIUM RIGHT
NOW.
SUPPOSED TO LAST ABOUT TWO
HOURS, SO IT'S GOING TO BE QUITE
A LENGTHY SERVICE.
THERE'S A NUMBER OF SPEAKERS, A
NUMBER OF READINGS FROM VARIOUS
RELIGIOUS TEXTS.
THERE WILL BE SOME AUDIENCE
PARTICIPATION IN THOSE READINGS
AS WELL.
I SEE A NUMBER OF PEOPLE WHO IT
LOOKS LIKE HAVE BEEN TOLD THAT
THERE'S NO MORE ROOM, SO IT
LOOKS LIKE A NUMBER OF PEOPLE
ARE LEAVING THIS HIGH SCHOOL.
WE'VE BEEN SEEING PEOPLE COME,
BUT EVEN AS WE SEE PEOPLE
LEAVING, WE SEE MORE PEOPLE
ARRIVING, MORE FAMILIES ARRIVI G
ARRIVING, EVEN BRINGING THEIR
LITTLE CHILDREN HOPING TO GET
INSIDE, BUT THERE ARE MANY
PLACES THROUGHOUT THIS TOWN
WHERE PEOPLE CAN PARTICIPATE IN
A SENSE AND CAN FEEL AS IF THEY
ARE ALL PART OF THIS.
WE'VE BEEN SEEING ONE OF THE
MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS DON LEMON IS
AT A FEW PLBLOCKS FROM THE HIGH
SCHOOL.
I SAW SOMEONE BRING 26 BALLOONS
AND TIE THEM DOWN AT A MEMORIAL.
PEOPLE BRINGING WHATEVER THEY
CAN, LITTLE ME MENTOS THEY FEEL
ARE IMPORTANT.
THEY JUST WANT TO TAKE A MOMENT
AND PAUSE AND REMEMBER.
WOLF?
>> YOU KNOW, ANDERSON, SORT OF A
VERY DIFFERENT CIRCUMSTANCE
INDEED, AND IT REMINDS ME IN THE
AFTERMATH OF THE OKLAHOMA CITY
BOMBING WHEN PRESIDENT CLINTON
WENT OUT TO OKLAHOMA CITY AND
DELIVERED A REALLY BEAUTIFUL,
POWERFUL ADDRESS THAT NOT ONLY
THE PEOPLE IN OKLAHOMA CITY, BUT
THROUGHOUT THE COUNTRY AND,
INDEED, THE WORLD, AN ADDRESS
THAT RESONATED.
THIS IS ONE OF THOSE KEY MOMENTS
FOR THIS PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES TO DO THE SAME THING AND
AS JESSICA HAS BEEN REPORTING
AND AS WE'VE HEARD THE PRESIDENT
PERSONALLY GOT INVOLVED.
HE'S AN EXCELLENT WRITER, AND HE
HAS WORKED HARD IN MAKING SURE
THAT THE WORDS HE WILL SAY
TONIGHT WILL HE BELIEVES
HOPEFULLY RESONATE NOT ONLY WITH
THE FOLKS OUT THERE, PEOPLE
WATCHING HERE IN THE UNITED
STATES AND AROUND THE WORLD, BUT
MOST IMPORTANTLY MAYBE BRING A
LITTLE BIT OF COMFORT, A LITTLE
BIT OF COMFORT, AND GOD KNOWS
THESE PEOPLE ARE GOING THROUGH
HELL RIGHT NOW, THE FAMILIES OF
THOSE WHO DIED, THE 26 PEOPLE
WHO WERE KI8D LLED SO BRUTALLY
FRIDAY MORNING.
SANJAY IS HERE AS WP.
SANJAY, THIS IS A CHALLENGE FOR
THIS PRESIDENT.
HE'S BEEN RE-ELECTED.
HE'S GOT FOUR YEARS AHEAD OF
HIM, BUT THIS IS ONE OF THOSE
SEMINAL MOMENTS THAT HISTORIANS
IN THE FUTURE WILL LOOK BACK AT
THIS SPEECH AND SAY, THIS WAS A
MOMENT THAT THE PRESIDENT
STEPPED UP.
>> THAT COMFORTER-IN-CHIEF IS
TERMINOLOGY THAT'S BEEN USED.
IT'S A QUESTION OF RIGHT NOW
HE'S MEETING WITH THESE PARENTS,
AS YOU MENTIONED, WOLF.
HE'S WORKING ON THESE REMARKS
HIMSELF.
MY GUESS IS HAVING WORKED IN
THAT CAPACITY IN A WHITE HOUSE
BEFORE, YOU KNOW, HIS REMARKS
MAY CHANGE EVEN AFTER HE MEETS
WITH THESE PARENTS AND IS SO
AFFECTED AND TOUCHED BY WHAT
HE'S HEARING FROM THEM.
SO I THINK THAT THE SORT OF --
WHAT WE HEAR FROM HIM I THINK IS
VERY MUCH GOING TO REFLECT THAT.
HE'S STILL MEETING WITH THEM
NOW, AS YOU POINT OUT.
THIS WAS SUPPOSED TO START
AROUND 7:00, BUT HE DOES NOT
WANT TO BE RUSHED.
HE WANTS TO HAVE THAT TIME TO
MEET WITH THESE FAMILIES.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT HE IS SAYING,
AND I DON'T KNOW, AS YOU SAID
EARLIER, WHAT HE COULD POSSIBLY
SAY, BUT THAT'S WHAT'S HAPPENING
RIGHT NOW.
>> WE SAW THOSE 26 GLASSES
THERE, MEMORIAL TO THE 26 WHO
WERE SO BRUTALLY ASSAULTED AND
KILLED FRIDAY MORNING.
20 CHILDREN AGES 6 AND 7, ALL
FIRST GRADERS, AND SIX TEACHERS,
SIX TEACHERS, ALL WOMEN, FOR NO
REASON, NO REASON AT ALL.
WE DON'T UNDERSTAND WHAT
HAPPENED, AND NOW WE'LL HEAR
FROM REPRESENTATIVES OF ALL THE
MAJOR FAITHS HERE IN THE UNITED
STATES AND THEY'RE GEARING UP.
WE'LL HAVE MUSIC AND WE'LL HAVE
POWERFUL WORDS.
REVEREND MATTHEW KREBIN, THE
SENIOR MINISTER OF THE NEWTOWN
CONGRESSIONAL CHURCH, UNITED
CHURCH OF CHRIST, HE WILL OPEN
UP.
I HAD AN OPPORTUNITY TO MEET
WITH HIM AT HIS CHURCH YESTERDAY
AND YOU SEE SOME OF THE CLERGY
THERE, INCLUDING THE RABBI WHO
IS THERE AS WELL.
YOU SEE HIM WEARING THE SKULL
CAP WITH HIS BACK TO US.
HE AND REVEREND KREBBIN, THEY
WERE BOTH INSIDE THE FIRE HALL
WHERE ALL THE FAMILIES GATHERED,
THE GOVERNOR WAS THERE, DANNEL
MALLOY, AND AT ONE POINT THE
GOVERNOR STARTED TELLING FAMILY
MEMBERS, PARENTS, WHO WAS ALIVE
AND WHO WASN'T ALIVE, AND, YOU
KNOW, AND BOTH THE MINISTER AND
THE RABBI SAID TO ME, IT WAS
ONE -- IT WAS THE MOST POWERFUL
MOMENT, THE SHOCK, AND THESE ARE
CLERGY, THEY'RE SUPPOSED TO
COMFORT.
THEY DIDN'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
>> THESE PARENTS, THEY DID NOT
KNOW, THEY WERE WAITING, HOPING,
SEEING CHILDREN COME OUT AND
HOPING THAT ONE OF THOSE
CHILDREN WOULD BE THEIRS, BUT
FOR SO MANY PARENTS THAT DIDN'T
HAPPEN, AND THE GOVERNOR WAS THE
ONE, YOU HEARD THIS MORNING,
WOLF, THAT ULTIMATELY TOLD THEM,
CONVEYED THAT INFORMATION, THAT
HORRIBLE INFORMATION TO THEM.
>> HE FELT IT WAS HIS
RESPONSIBILITY, GOVERNOR MALLOY,
HIS RESPONSIBILITY AS THE
GOVERNOR OF THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT TO DELIVER THIS
HORRENDOUS NEWS.
NO NEWS COULD BE WORSE.
CHILDREN BURY PARENTS.
PARENTS ARE NOT SUPPOSED TO BURY
THEIR CHILDREN, AND THIS IS AN
UNSPEAKABLE TRAGEDY THAT HAS
AFFLICTED -- THAT HAS IMPACTED
THIS SMALL OPPORTUNITY.
UNDER 30,000 PEOPLE LIVE HERE IN
NEWTOWN, AND, YOU KNOW, THEY'VE
ALL GATHERED HERE.
YOU SEE REPRESENTATIVES FROM ALL
THE FAITHS WHO HAVE COME TO
REMEMBER, TO REFLECT, AND THEY
HOPE BRING SOME COMFORT TO THOSE
WHO ARE IN MOURNING.
>> YOU KNOW, I DON'T KNOW HOW I
WOULD BEHAVE, WOLF.
I'M SURE YOU DON'T KNOW HOW YOU
WOULD EITHER IN A SITUATION LIKE
THIS.
I HAVE BEEN PRETTY AMAZED AT HOW
QUICKLY PEOPLE HAVE COME
TOGETHER.
WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT ROBBIE
PARKER, THIS 30-YEAR-OLD
PHYSICIAN'S ASSISTANT WHO LOST
HIS DAUGHTER EMILIE, I WAS,
AGAIN, AS I THINK SO MANY PEOPLE
WERE, STUNNED AND BLOWN AWAY BY
HOW FORGIVING HE WAS, HOW
COMPASSIONATE HE WAS, AND HOW --
I MEAN ACCEPT EPPSANCE IS PROBA
THE WRONG WORD BUT HE HAD
DEVELOPED A PLAN TO FORGIVE AND
TURN THIS TRAGEDY INTO SOMETHING
THAT COULD BE OF COMFORT TO
FAMILIES ALL OVER THE COUNTRY
THAT MAY GO THROUGH SOMETHING
LIKE THIS, THE LOSS OF A CHILD,
WOLF.
>> YEAH.
THERE'S NOTHING WORSE THAT ANY
PARENT, ANYONE COULD ENDURE THAN
LOSING A CHILD, AND WHEN WE SEE
THE PICTURES OF THESE LITTLE
KIDS AND WE SEE THEIR AGES, WE
SEE THEIR NAMES, WE
APPRECIATE -- I DON'T KNOW IF WE
COULD EVER APPRECIATE, BUT YOU
BEGIN TO SENSE THE ENORMITY OF
THE PAIN THESE PARENTS AND THEIR
LOVED ONES, GRANDPARENTS, ARE
GOING THROUGH RIGHT NOW, UNCLES
AND AUNTS.
YOU SEE THE CLERGY THERE ON THE
RIGHT OF YOUR SCREEN.
THAT'S SENATOR BLUMENTHAL, THE
JUNIOR SENATOR FROM CONNECTICUT,
SOON TO BE THE SENIOR SENATOR
FROM CONNECTICUT ONCE SENATOR
LIEBERMAN RETIRES AND HE WILL BE
LEAVING WITH THE NEW SENATE
SWORN IN IN JANUARY.
DON LEMON IS HERE ON THE STREETS
OF NEWTOWN HIMSELF WHERE ALL
THESE MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS HAVE
STRONG U
SPRUNG UP.
PEOPLE JUST FLOCKING TO NEWTOWN.
THEY WANT TO DO SOMETHING.
THEY AREN'T SURE EXACTLY WHAT
THEY CAN DO BUT THEY WANT TO DO
SOMETHING.
>> Reporter: AND NOT JUST FROM
THE AREA.
TIM IS HERE.
WAIT UNTIL YOU GUYS SEE THIS.
TIM IS HERE AND TIM IS FROM THE
CHICAGO AREA, RIGHT?
>> CORRECT.
LUTIAN CHURCH CHARITIES.
>> Reporter: AND THESE ARE
COMFORT DOGS YOU BROUGHT IN
YESTERDAY.
>> YES.
>> Reporter: WHY?
>> WE BROUGHT THEM IN TO BRING
COMFORT TO PEOPLE DURING
DISASTER TIMES OF LOSS WITH
PEOPLE.
THEY JUST COME IN FOR PEOPLE TO
PET.
THEY HAVE VESTS THAT SAY PLEASE
PET ME.
THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE DOING RIGHT
NOW.
>> Reporter: THIS IS LUTHER.
THAT'S PRINCE.
WHO IS THAT?
>> THAT'S RUTHIE, CHEWIE.
>> OR CHEWBACCA.
>> Reporter: DO YOU GO AROUND TO
DIFFERENT AREAS WHERE PEOPLE ARE
IN NEED TO DO THIS?
>> RIGHT.
WE DO IT IN DISASTER RESPONSE
SITUATIONS OR SITUATIONS LIKE
THIS AND WE PLACE DOGS IN
CHURCHES AND SCHOOLS.
WE HAVE 60 DOGS OUT THERE PLACED
IN SIX DIFFERENT STATES TO DO
THIS SORT OF THING.
>> Reporter: GET DOWN HERE WITH
ME.
TIM, IF YOU WANT TO SEE, LOOK AT
THE KIDS OVER HERE.
DAVE, GO OVER HERE.
IF YOU LOOK AT THE KIDS, THIS
BRINGS YOU JOY TO PET THIS DOG?
>> DEFINITELY.
>> Reporter: YEAH?
A SMILE -- LISTEN, I HAVEN'T
REALLY SEEN ANYONE SMILING OUT
HERE AND THESE DOGS SHOWED UP
AND THE KIDS STARTED SMILING.
THIS IS MARE MOM, KATHY.
WHEN YOUR KIDS SAW THE DOGS,
WHAT HAPPENED?
>> THEY LIT UP.
THEY LIT UP INSIDE AND THEY WERE
EVEN MORE EXCITED TO HEAR THAT
THEY WERE HERE TO SPREAD COMFORT
AND WE'RE RELIGIOUS, AND WE
BELIEVE THAT HAVING A SENSE OF
GOD BEING AROUND US BRINGS THAT
KIND OF COMFORT.
SO IT'S REALLY EXCITING THAT
PEOPLE CAME FROM CHICAGO.
>> Reporter: SHOW THE DOGS.
WHAT ARE THE AGES OF YOUR KIDS?
>> MY KIDS ARE 13, 12, AND 5.
WE'RE FROM MASSACHUSETTS.
>> Reporter: AND YOU ALSO
BROUGHT, YOU SAID, A SIGN.
>> WE BROUGHT THE ORANGE SIGN
WITH THE BLINKING LIGHTS.
WE JUST -- WE FELT LIKE IT WAS
IMPORTANT BECAUSE THERE WEREN'T
REALLY ANY GOOD WORDS TO FIX
PEOPLE'S GRIEF, THAT IF THEY SAW
AN ACTION, THAT PEOPLE LOVED
THEM ENOUGH TO COME AND WALK AND
REMEMBER THEIR CHILDREN THAT IT
WOULD HELP.
>> Reporter: THE SIGN SAYS WE
ARE HOLDING YOU CLOSE FROM
MASSACHUSETTS, BUT AGAIN WHEN
YOU LOOK AT, WOLF, YOU KNOW, THE
DOGS THAT CAN BRING A SMILE TO
THE FACE OF CHILDREN AND REALLY
TO EVERYONE, AND WHEN THESE DOGS
SHOWED UP HERE, EVERYONE STARTED
TO FLOCK AROUND THESE DOGS.
THEY STARTED TO PET THEM AND
THEY STARTED TO SMILE.
AND IT'S JUST ONE OF THE WAYS
HERE THAT PEOPLE ARE COMING
TOGETHER TO HELP THIS COMMUNITY
NOT ONLY FROM THE AREA BUT
REALLY FROM ALL OVER THE
COUNTRY.
YOU PUT SMILES ON PEOPLE'S
FACES.
DOES THAT MAKE YOU SMILE?
>> WE BRING MERCY AND COMPASSION
AND HELP PEOPLE TO DEAL.
>> Reporter: YOU COULDN'T HELP
YOURSELF WHEN YOU SAW WHAT
HAPPENED HERE?
>> WEE SEE THIS ALL THE TIME.
IF IT HELPS PEOPLE, THAT'S WHAT
WE'RE ABOUT.
>> Reporter: GO TOWARDS THE
DOGS.
YOU SEE EVERYONE HERE WALKING UP
AND THESE DOGS HAVE BECOME THE
CENTER OF ATTENTION.
I HAVE TO TELL YOU, IT DOES --
AND THEY'RE ALL AROUND THE
MEMORIAL OVER HERE.
IT DOES WARM MY HEART TO SEE
THIS BECAUSE EVERYONE HAS BEEN
SO SAD HERE, AND AS I SAID
YESTERDAY, I WAS TALKING TO
ANDERSON I BELIEVE, THAT I
HAVEN'T SEEN FACES LIKE THIS,
PEOPLE WHO SORT OF HAVE BLANK
LOOKS ON THEIR FACES SINCE I SAW
THE RESCUERS, QUITE FRANKLY,
DOWN AT 9/11, AND THEN THESE
DOGS REALLY ARE HELPING.
>> YES.
>> Reporter: I WISH THERE WERE
MORE.
>> A FEW WEEKS AGO WE WERE IN
NEW YORK CITY WITH THE DOGS AND
HELPING PEOPLE THERE AND THEN IN
NEW JERSEY, SAME THING.
WALKING THEM WITH CHILDREN.
>> Reporter: HOW MANY OTHER
ORGANIZATIONS ARE YOU AWARE OF
AROUND THE COUNTRY THAT DOES
THIS?
>> I'M NOT AWARE OF ANY THAT HAS
ORGANIZED PROGRAM THAT DOES
THIS.
>> Reporter: THE KIDS OVER HERE.
YOU SAID YOU'RE NOT AWARE OF
WHAT?
>> I'M NOT AWARE OF ANY THAT
DOES THIS, THAT BREEDS AND
TRAINS THEIR DOGS AND PLACES
THEM IN CHURCHES TO DO THIS.
THEY'RE AT NURSING HOMES,
HOSPITALS, WHEREVER, BUT
PARTICULARLY IN SITUATIONS LIKE
THIS WHERE YOU HAVE A TRAGEDY.
>> Reporter: YEAH.
WOLF, YOU KNOW, ONE MOMENT OF
JUST A LITTLE COMFORT HERE TO
THE PEOPLE WHO REALLY NEED SO
MUCH COMFORT AND SO MUCH HELP
AND JUST A DOG, A COUPLE DOGS
ARE ABLE TO DO IT.
I WISH THERE WERE MORE.
I WISH THERE WAS MORE WE COULD
DO FOR THE FOLKS HERE, BUT THIS
AT THE MOMENT, THIS IS AT LEAST
A LITTLE BIT.
>> YOU KNOW, THOSE DOGS, I'M
SURE, ARE VERY COMFORTING TO
SOME OF THE PEOPLE WHO ARE
THERE, DON.
THOSE ARE REALLY MOVING REPORTS
YOU'RE BRINGING US, AND WE'RE
GOING TO COME BACK TO YOU AS WE
AWAIT THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES, THE CLERGY,
THEY'RE GETTING READY FOR THIS
INTERFAITH MEMORIAL SERVICE.
WE'LL HEAR MUSIC, WE'LL HEAR
PRAYERS, WE'LL HEAR PASSAGES
FROM THE PSALMS AND WE'LL HEAR
FROM THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT.
WE'LL ALSO HEAR FROM THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES.
THIS WILL BE A VERY, VERY MOVING
SERVICE, AND WE CAN ONLY HOPE
AND PRAY THAT IT WILL BRING SOME
COMFORT TO THOSE WHO ARE IN
MOURNING RIGHT NOW.
ANDERSON COOPER IS WATCHING
WHAT'S GOING ON AS WELL.
ANDERSON?
>> YEAH, WOLF.
WE'RE OUTSIDE THE HIGH SCHOOL
WHERE THIS SERVICE IS GOING TO
TAKE PLACE.
I'M WITH DONNA MORRISSEY FROM
THE AMERICAN RED CROSS.
YOU HAVE BEEN HERE SINCE FRIDAY.
YOU CAME DOWN FROM BOSTON?
>> I DID, YES.
>> WHAT'S THE RED CROSS DOING
HERE?
>> I'M JOINED WITH 100 RED CROSS
VOLUNTEERS PROVIDING FOOD AND
WATER, ASSISTANCE TO NOT ONLY
THE AFFECTED FAMILIES BUT THE
FIRST RESPONDERS AND THE WHOLE
COMMUNITY.
ONE OF OUR BIG PUSHES IS TO
PROVIDE EMOTIONAL SUPPORT AND
COUNSELING FOR THOSE WHO ARE
DEALING WITH THE UNIMAGINABLE.
IN FACT, TONIGHT WE WERE HERE,
WE HANDED OUT ABOUT 400 OF THESE
LITTLE PUPPIES TO THE KIDS
WAITING IN LINE.
JUST SOMETHING THEY COULD HOLD
ONTO, PROVIDE SOME SENSE OF
COMFORT TO THEM.
>> THIS IS FOR THE KIDS WAITING
IN LINE TO GET INTO THE SERVICE.
>> WE HANDED OUT ABOUT 900
BLANKETS.
IT'S COLD, IT'S RAINY, AND
THEY'RE REALLY JUST DEALING WITH
SUCH AN UNIMAGINABLE TRAGEDY.
WE WANT TO BE HERE TO JUST
PROVIDE SOME LEVEL OF SUPPORT
DURING THESE DARK DAYS.
>> HOW DO COUNSELORS -- WHAT
DOES A COUNSELOR SAY AT A TIME
LIKE THIS?
>> WELL, MANY PEOPLE OBVIOUSLY
ARE OVERCOME WITH GRIEF, AND
THAT'S NORMAL FOR THEM TO FEEL
THAT WAY, AND SO WE HAVE
COUNSELORS MEETING ONE-ON-ONE.
WE HAVE PEOPLE PROVIDING
RESOURCES JUST TO BE THERE IN
THE MOMENT.
WE HAVE SOME PEOPLE THAT ARE --
HAVE BEEN PROFOUNDLY AFFECTED
DIRECTLY, HAVE LOST LOVED ONES.
OTHERS THAT JUST ARE IN A STATE
OF SHOCK BECAUSE, AS YOU KNOW,
DRIVING THROUGH THIS COMMUNITY,
IT'S, YOU KNOW, QUINTESSENTIAL
SMALL TOWN THAT YOU'D LOVE TO BE
A PART OF, YOU'D LOVE TO LIVE
IN.
YOU SEE KIDS, A CLOSE-KNIT
COMMUNITY, AND IT'S BEEN ROCKED.
EVEN FOR VETERAN VOLUNTEERS FOR
THE RED CROSS, THIS IS A
MAGNITUDE THAT WE'RE CARING FOR
OUR VOLUNTEERS AS WELL BECAUSE
IT'S JUST SO OVERWHELMING, BUT
YET WE NEED TO PUT OUR GRIEF
ASIDE, COME IN AND DO THE JOB
THAT WE'RE HERE TO DO, AND JUST
WRAP OUR ARMS AROUND THE PEOPLE
AND GIVE THEM A SHOULDER TO LEAN
ON.
>> YOU'RE ALSO REACHING OUT TO
FIRST RESPONDERS.
>> WE ARE, AND I'M SO AMAZED BY
THE PROFESSIONALISM.
YESTERDAY THERE WAS A POLICE
OFFICER IN FRONT OF ME, AND THIS
WOMAN CAME UP AND LITERALLY
COLLAPSED INTO HIS ARMS, AND HE
JUST WRAPPED HIMSELF AROUND HER
AND WAS A STEADY FORCE.
AND THESE ARE FOLKS THAT ARE THE
FABRIC OF THE COMMUNITY.
THEY HAVE KIDS, AND YET THEY'RE
HERE DOING THE JOB THAT THEY'VE
BEEN TRAINED TO DO.
SO THIS IS BIGGER THAN ONE
ORGANIZATION, ONE GROUP, BUT IF
THERE WAS ONE MESSAGE WE COULD
BRING TO THE COMMUNITY HERE,
THAT IS THAT PEOPLE ACROSS THIS
COUNTRY AND BEYOND ARE SENDING A
MESSAGE OF LOVE AND HOPE AND
SUPPORT, AND THE RED CROSS IS
HERE AND WE'RE GOING TO STAY
HERE AS LONG AS NEEDED.
>> AND I CERTAINLY HOPE PEOPLE
IN THIS COMMUNITY FEEL THAT
BECAUSE I HAVE HEARD FROM PEOPLE
ALL AROUND THE WORLD, AND THIS
IS -- THIS HAS BEEN THE FRONT
PAGE REPORTS IN ALL THE
NEWSPAPERS ALL AROUND THE WORLD,
AND WE'VE SEEN AN OUTPOURING OF
PEOPLE, AND I HOPE THAT THE
PEOPLE HERE FEEL THAT BECAUSE
THERE'S A LOT OF LOVE AND A LOT
OF PRAYERS AND SUPPORT FOR THEM.
>> ALL OF THE PEOPLE THAT WE MET
WITH AS WE HANDED THEM A DOG OR
A SNACK OR WATER OR A BLANKET
TONIGHT WERE THANKING US.
THIS IS THE LEAST WE CAN DO.
WE ARE HERE DURING THEIR TIME OF
NEED.
DRIVING THROUGH TOWN TONIGHT,
THERE WAS A VILLAGIL OF 26 LITT
ANGELS, CARDS PEOPLE WERE
SIGNING.
THERE'S SUCH AN OUTPOURING OF
COMMUNITY SPIRIT IN THE FACE OF
SUCH HORROR, AND SO OUR HOPE IS
THAT WE CAN JOIN SHOLDER TO
SHOULDER AND ARM IN ARM AND JUST
BE HERE IN THEIR MOMENT OF NEED.
>> YOU CAME FROM -- BEFORE THIS
YOU WERE AT HURRICANE SANDY
RESPONDING TO THAT.
WHAT IS IT LIKE FOR YOU TO SEE
THIS?
>> WHEN WE RECEIVED THE CALL
THAT THERE WAS A REPORT OF A
SHOOTING AT A SCHOOL, OUR HEARTS
SKIPPED A BEAT, AND WITHIN A
COUPLE HOURS WE KNEW THAT WE
WERE NEEDED.
WE ALREADY HAD LOCAL RED
CROSSERS HERE AND I WAS FROM
BOSTON.
WE JUMPED IN A CAR AND JUST
STARTED HEADING THIS DIRECTION
NOT KNOWING WHAT WE WERE GOING
TO FIND.
WHEN WE FIRST DROVE IN, WHAT
STRUCK ME WAS THE HOUSES OF
WORSHIP THAT WERE OVERFLOWING,
THE YOUNG KIDS, TOO YOUNG TO
HAVE TO DEAL WITH THIS WITH
THEIR HEADS HUNG LOW, AND THE
HUSH.
THERE WAS A VERY HUSH OF SILENCE
AS WE DROVE IN.
THE NEXT DAY TO SEE WHAT SHOULD
HAVE BEEN A JOYOUS HOLIDAY TIME
AND YET PEOPLE WERE DEALING WITH
LITTLE ONES, JUST LITTLE ONES
TAKEN FAR TOO SOON.
IT JUST WAS SOMETHING THAT YOU
HAD TO KIND OF GET AHOLD OF
YOURSELF.
FOR ME PERSONALLY, I WANTED TO
JUST SIT DOWN AND CRY MY EYES
OUT, RIGHT?
I THOUGHT OF MY OWN NIECES.
I THOUGHT OF LITTLE ONES AROUND
THE HOLIDAYS WHO SHOULD BE OUT,
YOU KNOW, WITH SONGS AND LIGHTS
AND ENJOYING WHAT LIFE HAS TO
OFFER, BUT YET I FELT AS A RED
CROSS VOLUNTEER I NEEDED TO JUST
KIND OF COMPARTMENTALIZE, PUT IT
ASIDE, AND GO AND DO WHAT WE
NEEDED TO DO.
BUT IT'S FAR BEYOND WHAT I HAVE
EVER BEEN ON AND THE DEPLOYMENTS
I HAVE DONE FOR THE RED CROSS,
BUT WE'RE HERE, WE TRAIN YEAR
ROUND FOR THIS AND THAT'S WHAT
WE DO AS A HUMANITARIAN
ORGANIZATION, WE COME WHEN THE
NEED IS THE GREAT HE EST.
>> I DON'T KNOW ANYBODY WHO HAS
BEEN HERE FOR A FEW DAYS THAT
HASN'T SHED A LOT OF TEARS.
>> THANK YOU FOR ALL YOUR DOING.
>> THANK YOU.
REMARKABLE WORK.
WOLF, AGAIN, THAT'S THE SCENE
HERE.
WE'VE BEEN TOLD ABOUT 15 MINUTES
FROM NOW IS WHEN THE SERVICE IS
GOING TO BEGIN.
WE'VE BEEN GIVEN A 15-MINUTE
WARNING TO THE START OF THE
SERVICE.
SO JUST WANT TO REMIND OUR
VIEWERS WE WILL BE BROADCASTING
THE ENTIRE SERVICE WITHOUT ANY
INTERRUPTION.
WE WON'T BE TALKING OVER THE
SERVICE OR ANYTHING LIKE THAT.
WE KNOW HOW ANNOYING THAT CAN BE
FOR VIEWERS.
YOU WILL BE HEARING THE SERVICE
AS THE PEOPLE INSIDE ARE
EXPERIENCING IT THEMSELVES, AND
OUTSIDE THE SCENE AT THE HIGH
SCHOOL AGAIN, MORE PEOPLE STILL
CONTINUE TO COME AND THERE IS AN
OVERFLOW ROOM WE'RE TOLD, BUT WE
BELIEVE THAT'S ABOUT AT CAPACITY
AS WELL BECAUSE IT LOOKS LIKE A
NUMBER OF PEOPLE HAVE BEEN KIND
OF TURNED AWAY AND ARE MOVING
BACK TO THEIR VEHICLES, WOLF.
>> PEOPLE ARE INSIDE THAT
AUDITORIUM, ANDERSON AT THE HIGH
SCHOOL.
YOU'RE JUST OUTSIDE THAT HIGH
I'M DOWN THE STREET FROM THE
HIGH SCHOOL.
THIS IS A SERVICE THAT I THINK
ALL OF US WILL ALWAYS REMEMBER
AND REPRESENTATIVES OF ALL THE
MAJOR FAITHS WILL PARTICIPATE
WITH PRAYERS, WITH MUSIC, AND
WE'LL ALSO HEAR, OF COURSE, FROM
THE PRESIDENT.
HE'S STILL COMFORTING SOME OF
THE FAMILY MEMBERS, THE PARENTS
OF THOSE WHO WERE KILLED, THE
LOVED ONES, SIX ADULTS, ALL
WOMEN, 20 CHILDREN BRUTALLY
KILLED FRIDAY MORNING AT THIS
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AND WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT
THESE VICTIMS.
BROOKE BALDWIN IS STANDING BY.
BROOKE, YOU'VE BEEN GETTING SOME
AMAZING STORIES OF SOME OF THESE
PEOPLE WHO WERE SO SENSELESSLY
KILLED AT THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
FRIDAY MORNING.
>> Reporter: IT IS ABSOLUTELY
HEARTBREAKING, WOLF, WHEN YOU
LOOK AT THIS LIST OF THESE 20
YOUNG VICTIMS AND NEVER HAVE I
EVER SEEN A LIST WHERE YOU LOOK
AT THE AGES AND THEY ARE ALL IN
THE SINGLE DIGITS.
SO AS WE LEARN MUCH MORE ABOUT
THESE LITTLE ONES WHO ARE NO
LONGER WITH US, WE'RE LEARNING
ALSO ABOUT THE HEROES.
IN FACT, WE'RE LEARNING ABOUT
THIS FIRST GRADE TEACHER, VICKI,
SHE WENT BY VICKI, IT'S VICTORIA
SOTO.
HER LITTLE SISTER CARLY IS
INSIDE THAT MEMORIAL.
SHE JUST TWEETED ABOUT HER BIG
SISTER.
CARLY SOTO TWEETED, GOING TO
MEET MR. OBAMA.
WISH VICKI WAS HERE.
DRESSED IN ALL MY BIG SISTER'S
CLOTHES LOOKING CUTE IN HONOR OF
SISSY.
HER SISTER, VICKI, WAS THAT
FIRST GRADE TEACHER WHO QUICKLY
THOUGHT ON HER FEET AND
PROTECTED AS MANY OF HER LITTLE
6 AND 7-YEAR-OLDS AS SHE
POSSIBLY COULD.
IN FACT, POLICE LATER FOUND
SEVEN OF THOSE YOUNGSTERS SORT
OF HUDDLED SURVIVING IN A CLOSET
IN THAT FIRST GRADE CLASSROOM.
WE KNOW THAT ACCORDING TO
VICKI'S COUSIN, QUOTE, SHE
INSTINCTIVELY WENT INTO ACTION
WHEN A MONSTER CAME INTO A
CLASSROOM AND TRIED TO PROTECT
THE KIDS SHE LOVED SO MUCH.
WE WANT THE PUBLIC TO KNOW THAT
VICKI WAS A HERO.
LET ME TELL YOU ABOUT ANOTHER
HERO, THE PRINCIPAL.
DONNA HOCHSPRUNG, 47 YEARS OF
AGE.
HAD BEEN AT THIS ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL FOR TWO YEARS.
SHE WAS PASSIONATE.
SHE LOVED CHILDREN.
THE CHILDREN LOVED HER.
SHE HAD A SMILE ON HER FACE.
THIS ONE FRIEND SAYS SHE WAS A
TOUGH WOMAN BUT A TOUGH WOMAN IN
THE RIGHT SORT OF WAY, AND
SECURITY WAS A PRIORITY FOR HER.
AGAIN, SHE HAD BEEN THERE FOR
TWO YEARS.
SHE HAD ALREADY INSTALLED THIS
NEW SECURITY SYSTEM TO MAKE SURE
IF THERE WERE TO BE A VISITOR AT
THE SCHOOL ONCE THE FRONT DOORS
LOCKED AT 9:30 IN THE MORNING,
YOU HAD TO RING THE DOORBELL.
SHE LUNGED AT THE SHOOTER FRIDAY
MORNING ALONG WITH THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST AND THAT IS WHEN
SHE WAS TAKEN DOWN.
SHE WAS YELLING ACCORDING TO
REPORTS TO A TEACHER DOWN THE
HALL, CLOSE THE DOOR, LOCK THE
DOOR FROM THE INSIDE.
SHE WAS MARRIED, TWO DAUGHTERS.
SHE'LL LEAVE BEHIND TWO
DAUGHTERS AND THREE STEP
DAUGHTERS AND JUST QUICKLY HERE,
THE 30-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER HAS
SAID THIS, CHRISTINA, MY MOM WAS
TAKEN TRAGICALLY FROM ME, BUT
SHE WENT DOWN IN A BLAZE OF
GLORY THAT TRULY REPRESENTS WHO
SHE WAS.
DAWN HOCK STRUHSPRUNGHOCHSPRUNG.
56-YEAR-OLD MARY SHERLACH, SHE
WAS THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST.
SHE WAS WITH THE PRINCIPAL WHEN
THEY HEARD THE POP, POP, POP
FRIDAY MORNING RIGHT AROUND
9:30, AND, AGAIN, SHE TRIED TO
SEE WHAT WAS THE MATTER, AND
THAT IS WHEN SHE WAS KILLED.
SHE HAS BEEN MARRIED ACCORDING
TO WHAT WE'VE LEARNED ABOUT HER,
SHE HAD BEEN MARRIED FOR MORE
THAN THREE DECADES, AND SHE WAS
THE PROUD PARENT OF TWO
DAUGHTERS.
SHE LOVED GARDENING, READING,
AND GOING TO THE THEATER.
THESE ARE JUST A COUPLE OF THE
NAMES AND JUST TO REITERATE WHAT
EVERYBODY HAS SEEN AND
EXPERIENCED AROUND TOWN, I GOT
TO NEWTOWN AND JUST WALKING
AROUND THESE VIGILS NOT A DRY
EYE IN SIGHT.
SEEING NOT ONLY ADULTS DROPPING
OFF ORNAMENTS TO PLACE ON THE
TREES OR CANDLES OR PRESENTS,
YOU SEE THEIR ITTY-BITTY
CHILDREN HAND IN HAND WITH THEIR
PARENTS, 4, 5, 6 YEARS OF AGE
WALKING AROUND WITH STUFFED
ANIMALS, PERHAPS THAT THEY TOOK
FROM THEIR OWN TREE JUST TO BE
ABLE TO GIVE IN HONOR OF THESE
YOUNGSTERS SO TRAGICALLY TAKEN
FROM US WAY, WAY TOO EARLY.
WOLF?
>> BROOKE, THANK YOU.
I WANT TO SHOW OUR VIEWERS THIS
PICTURE HERE.
TAKE A LOOK AT THIS.
SANJAY IS WITH ME AS WELL.
THIS IS THE RIBBON A LOT OF
THESE PEOPLE ARE WEARING.
IT'S A RIBBON THAT THEY'VE
ATTACHED TO THEIR CLOTHING.
IT SHOWS NOT ONLY THE RIBBON BUT
IT SHOWS A LITTLE ANGEL RIGHT IN
THE MIDDLE THERE IF YOU CAN GET
UP CLOSE, YOU CAN SEE THAT
LITTLE ANGEL, AND IF YOU SEE
PEOPLE WEARING THIS RIBBON AT
THIS MEMORIAL SERVICE RIGHT NOW,
YOU'LL KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON.
SANJAY, I'M HOPING THIS WILL
BRING SOME COMFORT, A LITTLE BIT
OF COMFORT, BUT THERE'S NOTHING
REALLY THAT WE CAN DO.
YOU SEE THESE ARE PEOPLE
OBVIOUSLY WHO ARE SUFFERING
RIGHT NOW EVEN AS WE AWAIT THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
AND REPRESENTATIVES OF THE
CLERGY TO DELIVER SOME WORDS.
>> IT'S A SMALL TOWN, WOLF.
YOU REALLY -- YOU CAN REALLY SEE
HOW WELL PEOPLE REALLY KNOW EACH
OTHER.
MAYBE SOME OF THESE PEOPLE ARE
SEEING EACH OTHER FOR THE FIRST
TIME.
YOU CAN SEE OBVIOUSLY THE
SERVICE IS STARTING TO BEGIN
HERE, WOLF.
>> YOU SEE SOME OF THE PEOPLE
ARRIVING.
WE'RE WAITING FOR THE PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED STATES.
HE'LL BE ARRIVING MOMENTARILY.
SOME OF THE FIRST RESPONDERS ARE
THERE AS WELL.
THE PRESIDENT MET WITH THEM.
LET'S LISTEN.
[ APPLAUSE ]
AND WE WANT TO WELCOME OUR
VIEWERS IN THE UNITED STATES AND
AROUND THE WORLD.
SPECIAL COVERAGE OF A MEMORIAL
SERVICE, AN INTERFAITH MEMORIAL
SERVICE, HONORING THOSE WHO WERE
SO SENSELESSLY KILLED,
SENSELESSLY KILLED FRIDAY
MORNING AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
HERE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
YOU SEE AT THIS HIGH SCHOOL
FIRST RESPONDERS HAVE ARRIVED.
THOSE WHO WERE INVOLVED IN
DEALING WITH THIS CRISIS AS IT
UNFOLDED.
PEOPLE STOOD AND GAVE THEM A
STANDING OVATION AS THEY
ARRIVED.
THE PRESIDENT WILL BE THERE
MOMENTARILY.
THE GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT WILL
BE THERE.
REPRESENTATIVES OF VARIOUS
FAITHS WILL BE SPEAKING,
DELIVERING PRAYERS, WE'LL BE
HEARING MUSIC.
THIS WILL BE AN EMOTIONAL AND
MOVING CEREMONY, MEMORIAL
SERVICE, ESPECIALLY BECAUSE WE
KNOW THAT PARENTS OF SOME OF THE
CHILDREN WHO WERE KILLED,
RELATIVES OF SOME OF THE ADULTS
WHO WERE KILLED WILL BE IN THIS
AUDIENCE.
MANY OF THEM HAVE JUST MET WITH
THE PRESIDENT WHO CAME HERE TO
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, TO OFFER
SOME COMFORT.
ANDERSON COOPER IS WITH US AS
WELL.
ANDERSON?
>> AND WE, OF COURSE, WILL BE
BRINGING YOU THIS ENTIRE
SERVICE.
WE ANTICIPATE IT LASTING ABOUT
TWO HOURS OR SO.
WE WILL BRING YOU THE ENTIRE
SERVICE UNINTERRUPTED WITHOUT
COMMENTARY, BUT WE ARE JUST
AWAITING THE START OF IT WHICH
WE BELIEVE IS JUST A MINUTE OR
TWO AWAY.
LET'S LISTEN IN AGAIN AS WE SEE
MORE RESPONDERS ARRIVING.
LET'S LISTEN TO THE CROWD
APPLAUD.
[ APPLAUSE ]
FOR MANY THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
THEY HAVE SEEN SOME OF THESE
FIRST RESPONDERS SINCE FRIDAY.
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS ALREADY ON
SCENE IN THE HIGH SCHOOL, HAS
BEEN MEETING INDIVIDUALLY AND
PRIVATELY WITH FAMILY MEMBERS OF
THOSE WHO HAVE LOST THEIR
CHILDREN AND ALSO FAMILY MEMBERS
OF THE TEACHERS AND THE SCHOOL
ADMINISTRATORS WHO ALSO LOST
THEIR LIVES, THE SIX ADULTS, THE
20 CHILDREN KILLED IN THAT
SCHOOL.
OUR JESSICA YELLIN IS ALSO
STANDING BY, OUR CHIEF WHITE
HOUSE CORRESPONDENT.
THERE IS AN OVERFLOW ROOM FOR
PEOPLE WHO WERE NOT ABLE TO GET
INTO THAT AUDITORIUM, JESSICA.
>> THERE'S AN OVERFLOW ROOM AND
A GROUP OF PEOPLE THE PRESIDENT
HAS BEEN MEETING WITH.
HE'S BEEN OBVIOUSLY TAKING HIS
TIME TALKING TO THEM PRIVATELY.
ANDERSON, I CAN ALSO TELL YOU
THE PRESIDENT TOOK HIS TIME
WORKING ON THESE REMARKS.
I'M TOLD HE WORKED ON THEM
HIMSELF.
HE WROTE THEM PERSONALLY AND ON
HIS WAY HE WORKED ON THEM AS HE
FLEW HERE AND ON THE CAR RIDE
OVER HERE.
AND THE SPEECHWRITER WHO HELPED
HIM PREPARE THESE REMARKS IS THE
SAME PERSON WHO HELPED HIM WRITE
GABBY GIFFORDS SPEECH AND HIS
EULOGY FOR SENATOR TED KENNEDY,
HIS MENTOR.
>> WE HAVE JUST BEEN GIVEN A
NOTICE THAT THE SERVICE WILL
BEGIN IN ABOUT FOUR OR FIVE
MINUTES FROM NOW.
THAT IS WHAT EVERYBODY IS NOW
SEATED WAITING FOR THE START OF
THIS SERVICE.
SANJAY GUPTA IS ALSO STANDING BY
WITH US AS WELL AS WOLF BLITZER
WATCHING ALONG WITH US, AND
SANJAY, YOU WERE OUT AT THE
CRISIS CENTER YESTERDAY WHERE
MANY FAMILIES HAVE GONE BRINGING
THEIR CHILDREN JUST TO TRY TO
GET SOME ADVICE ON HOW TO TALK
TO THEIR CHILDREN AND PROBABLY
MANY PEOPLE WHO VISITED AT THAT
CRISIS CENTER ARE PROBABLY IN
THAT ROOM TONIGHT TO TAKE PART
IN THIS SERVICE.
>> YES, THERE'S NO QUESTION,
ANDERSON.
I DIDN'T REALLY KNOW WHAT TO
EXPECT GOING TO A CRISIS CENTER
LIKE THAT.
THIS WAS SO RAW STILL FOR SO
MANY PEOPLE, BUT I WILL TELL
YOU, YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
PEOPLE SHOWED UP.
THERE WERE AT LEAST 100 CARS AT
THAT TIME IN THE PARKING LOT.
THIS WAS YESTERDAY AFTERNOON,
AND PEOPLE WENT IN AND THEY
STAYED IN THERE FOR SOME TIME,
AND CLEARLY, YOU KNOW, THE
SERVICES OF PSYCHIATRISTS,
PSYCHOLOGISTS, PEDIATRIC
COUNSELORS, CHILD COUNSELORS
WERE THERE, BUT PEOPLE WERE
GOING IN, WOLF, AND THEY WERE
STAYING THERE, AND I THINK, YOU
KNOW, PART OF THE COUNSELING I
THINK OBVIOUSLY VERY IMPORTANT,
BUT, YOU KNOW, JUST WATCHING
WHAT'S HAPPENING HERE IN THIS
SMALL TOWN WHERE PEOPLE KNOW
EACH OTHER, THEY RAISED EACH
OTHER'S KIDS.
THEY DON'T LIVE IN THESE
INDIVIDUAL SILOS LIKE SO OFTEN
HAPPENS IN BIG CITIES.
THIS IS A COMMUNITY THAT YOU CAN
TELL IS VERY TIGHT-KNIT, AND
WHEN THEY WENT TO A CRISIS
CENTER, AS THEY CALL IT, I THINK
A LOT OF THE COMFORT THEY WERE
GETTING WAS JUST SIMPLY BEING
AROUND EACH OTHER AND BEING
ACKNOWLEDGED THEY WEREN'T GOING
THROUGH THIS ALONE, THAT THIS
WAS SOMETHING THAT THEY WERE
GOING TO GO THROUGH AND GET
THROUGH TOGETHER.
>> AND I DON'T KNOW HOW PEOPLE,
YOU KNOW, EXPERTS, COUNSELORS
CAN PREPARE.
ARE THEY TRAINED TO DEAL WITH A
HORRENDOUS CRIME LIKE THIS,
SOMEBODY JUST GOING INTO AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND KILLING
TEACHERS AND FIRST GRADERS?
HOW DO YOU PREPARE?
ARE THERE GRADUATE SCHOOLS IN
CRISIS CENTERS THAT CAN DEAL
WITH THIS KIND OF SITUATION?
>> ONE OF THE MOST RENOWNED
CENTERS IN THE COUNTRY ACTUALLY
IS AT YALE, NEW HAVEN.
THEY WOULD A PHONE LINE OPEN.
THE CRISIS CENTER WAS DANBURY
HOSPITAL.
I THINK YOU'RE RIGHT, IN MEDICAL
TRAINING IT'S OBVIOUSLY HARD TO
TRAIN COMPLETELY FOR THESE
THINGS, BUT THE IDEA THAT YOU
WANT TO TRY AND PREVENT
PSYCHOLOGICAL DAMAGE AS MUCH AS
POSSIBLE, AND THAT INVOLVES THIS
COUNSELING EARLY ON.
>> YOU KNOW, WE'RE GOING TO
HEAR, ANDERSON, WE'RE GOING TO
HEAR REPRESENTATIVES OF
DIFFERENT FAITHS SPEAKING,
DELIVERING PRAYERS TONIGHT, AND
MANY OF THEM DEAL WITH THIS
QUESTION.
IT'S A FUNDAMENTAL QUESTION.
YOU KNOW, HOW CAN GOD ALLOW
THESE KINDS OF TRAGEDIES TO TAKE
PLACE?
AND THERE IS NO ANSWER FOR THIS.
VARIOUS RELIGIONS HAVE DIFFERENT
CONCEPTS ON THIS, BUT THIS IS A
CRIME COMMITTED NOT BY GOD.
IT'S A CRIME COMMITTED BY MAN,
AND THESE CRIMES HAPPEN.
>> THE CROWD HEARING A PIANO
PLAYING UP AT THE FRONT OF THE
AUDITORIUM.
♪
>> THE MUSIC MINISTER AT THE
TRINITY EPISCOPAL CHURCH, FIONA
SMITH SUTHERLAND, IS BRINGING
THIS MUSIC TO GATHER EVERYONE
TOGETHER.
THE PRESIDENT WILL BE WALKING IN
SHORTLY, AND THEN WE WILL HEAR
THE REVEREND MATTHEW CREBB AND
THE SENIOR MINISTER OF THE
NEWTOWN CONGREGATIONAL CHURCH
WHO WILL BE OPENING UP THIS
VIGIL, THIS SPECIAL MEMORIAL
SERVICE, AND THEN HE'LL BE
FOLLOWED BY THE RABBI HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
HE WILL READ A SCRIPTURE FROM
PSALM 46.
ALL OF THESE PRAYERS, ANDERSON,
WILL HAVE SPECIAL MEANING AND
PRESUMABLY WILL BRING, WE HOPE,
WE CAN ONLY HOPE AND PRAY, THAT
THEY WILL BRING SOME COMFORT TO
THOSE WHO ARE IN MOURNING.
♪
>> YOU KNOW, THERE ARE GOING TO
BE READ FRTIINGS FROM THE EPISC
CHURCH, THE KORAN, THE LORD'S
PRAYER.
AS YOU SAY, THIS IS A SERVICE
THAT IS GOING TO INCORPORATE
MANY DIFFERENT FAITHS.
WOLF, YOU WERE ASKING HOW DO YOU
COME TO TERMS WITH SOMETHING
LIKE THIS, AND I THINK AS YOU
SAY, DIFFERENT FAITHS ARE GOING
TO HAVE DIFFERENT APPROACHES TO
THIS, BUT IT'S GOING TO BE A
TRULY DIVERSE SERVICE TONIGHT.
>> WE WILL ALSO HAVE A SPECIAL
READING, A PRAYER FROM JOHN
WOODALL.
I MET WITH HIM YESTERDAY.
HE'S A LEADER OF THE BAHA'I
COMMUNITY.
HE'S ALSO A PSYCHOLOGIST AND HAS
WORKED IN CRISIS CENTERS OVER
THE YEARS.
A VERY INTELLIGENT MAN.
HE WILL BE DELIVERING A SPECIAL
PRAYER AS WELL AND OTHERS
REPRESENTATIVE OF THE -- OF
VARIOUS FAITHS WILL BE SPEAKING,
AND THEN, OF COURSE, AT THE END
OF THE SERVICE HERE, WE'LL HEAR
FROM THE GOVERNOR, DANNEL
MALLOY.
WE'LL HEAR FROM THE PRESIDENT OF
THE UNITED STATES, AND A FINAL
PRAYER FROM THE REVEREND BOB
WEISS.
HE'S PASTOR OF THE ST. ROSE OF
LIMA ROMAN CATHOLIC CHURCH HERE.
ALL THE FAITHS, SANJAY, ARE
REALLY REPRESENTED HERE.
IF YOU TAKE A LOOK AT THE LIST
OF THE 26 PEOPLE WHO WERE
SLAUGHTERED AT THAT ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, IT REPRESENTS AMERICA.
THERE ARE REPRESENTATIVES OF ALL
THE FAITHS THERE AS WELL.
>> NO QUESTION, AND I WILL TELL
YOU JUST GETTING A LITTLE
GLIMPSE OF THE FIRST RESPONDERS
SORT OF COMING IN AND HEARING
THE SORT OF RECEPTION THEY GOT.
WOLF, I CAN TELL YOU A LOT OF
TIMES AFTER SOMETHING LIKE THIS
HAPPENS, YOU DON'T OFTEN TIMES
HAVE TIME TO REFLECT ON
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
AND THOSE EMOTIONAL HUGS, THESE
GUYS COMING TOGETHER, IT'S
REMARKABLE.
>> ALL RIGHT.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
THE PRESIDENT IS ABOUT TO WALK
IN.
THE SERVICE IS ABOUT TO BEGIN.
THE MUSIC MINISTER AT THE
TRINITY EPISCOPAL CHURCH IS
PERFORMING NOW.
LET'S LISTEN IN.
♪
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> FIONA SMITH SUTHERLAND, THE
MUSIC MINISTER HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WITH GATHERING
MUSIC AS THEY'RE CALLING IT FOR
THIS INTERFAITH PRAYER VIGIL
THAT'S ABOUT TO BEGIN WITH THE
REVEREND MATTHEW CREBB, THE
SENIOR MINUTE STORE OF THE
NEWTOWN CON GGREGATIONAL CHURCH
WILL BE WELCOMING EVERYONE WITH
OPENING REMARKS AND THEN WE WILL
BE HEARING PRAYERS FROM VARIOUS
MINISTERS AND REPRESENTATIVES OF
THE MAJOR FAITHS HERE IN THE
UNITED STATES.
WE'RE AWAITING THE PRESIDENT,
WHO HAS BEEN VERY BUSY OVER THE
PAST COUPLE HOURS.
HE'S BEEN MEETING WITH THE
FAMILY MEMBERS OF THE VICTIMS
WHO WERE SO BRUTALLY KILLED
FRIDAY MORNING AT A SMALL
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
HE'S BEEN TRYING TO BRING SOME
COMFORT TO THEM.
HE'S BEEN MEETING WITH THEM.
HE'S ALSO MET WITH
REPRESENTATIVES OF THE FIRST
RESPONDERS, THE POLICE, THE
FIREFIGHTERS, OTHERS, THE
EMERGENCY MEDICAL PERSONNEL WHO
IMMEDIATELY CAME TO THE SCENE.
YOU SAW SOME OF THEM WALKING IN
TO THIS HIGH SCHOOL, THE NEWTOWN
HIGH SCHOOL, WHERE THESE PEOPLE
HAVE GATHERED FOR WHAT IS
EXPECTED TO BE A VERY POWERFUL,
EMOTIONAL MEMORIAL SERVICE.
ANDERSON COOPER IS STANDING BY.
HE'S RIGHT OUTSIDE THE HIGH
SCHOOL.
ANDERSON, I KNOW THIS HAS BEEN
DELAYED, BUT IT'S FOR A VERY
GOOD REASON.
THE PRESIDENT IS WITH THOSE
FAMILIES AND WE CAN ONLY IMAGINE
HOW PAINFUL THIS MUST BE FOR ALL
OF THEM.
>> AND THERE ARE DOZENS OF
FAMILIES WHO HAVE NOT BEEN ABLE
TO GET INTO THE HIGH SCHOOL WHO
ARE NOW LEAVING THE BUILDING.
SOME OF THEM WRAPPED IN BLANKETS
GIVEN TO THEM BY THE AMERICAN
RED CROSS.
IT IS VERY COLD OUT.
THERE'S RAIN OUTSIDE.
BUT A LOT OF PEOPLE STILL,
DESPITE THE ELEMENTS, WANTED TO
BE HERE, WANTED TO BEAR WITNESS
TO THIS, TO SHARE IN THE TEARS,
TO SHARE IN THE REMEMBRANCES OF
THOSE WHOSE LIVES HAVE BEEN
LOST.
♪
PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS BEEN ON
SCENE FOR AT LEAST AN HOUR OR SO
TALKING WITH THE FAMILIES AND
JUST ITTHE FAMILIES OF THE
CHILDREN, OF THE SCHOOL
ADMINISTRATORS, THE FAMILIES OF
THE TEACHERS WHO LOST THEIR
LIVES, THE PRINCIPAL AS WELL,
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG.
WE ANTICIPATE ABOUT A TWO-HOUR
SERVICE ONCE IT ACTUALLY BEGINS.
WE'LL BE BRINGING IT TO YOU, OF
COURSE, UNINTERRUPTED, AND OUR
COVERAGE, OF COURSE, WILL
CONTINUE ON AFTER THAT WELL INTO
THE NIGHT.
THERE'S ALSO A NUMBER OF
MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS WHICH ARE
VISIBLE AND SOME OUTSIDE THE
HIGH SCHOOL THAT HAVE BEEN
GROWING IN SIZE ALL DAY LONG,
AND A NUMBER OF -- THE ONE YOU
SEE THERE IS DOWNTOWN NEWTOWN.
A VERY SMALL, SMALL COMMUNITY
HERE.
WE'VE JUST BEEN GIVEN A
TWO-MINUTE WARNING, THAT THE
SERVICE WILL BEGIN, BUT WE'VE
BEEN GIVEN SOME WARNINGS IN THE
PASTZ THAT HAVE CONTINUED TO  E
AND IT'S FOR A VERY GOOD REASON,
THE PRESIDENT HAS BEEN MEETING
WITH FAMILY MEMBERS.
HE DOESN'T IN ANY WAY WANT TO
CUT THAT SHORT.
WE'VE BEEN TOLD THE SERVICE WILL
BEGIN IF TWO MINUTES FROM NOW.
>> AND WE WILL BE HEARING
PRAYERS, MEANINGFUL PRAYERS,
VARIOUS PSALMS, VARIOUS
SCRIPTURES.
IN ADDITION, WE'LL BE HEARING
FROM REPRESENTATIVES OF THE
ISLAMIC CENTER HERE IN NEWTOWN,
AS WELL A READING FROM THE KORAN
AND A SPECIAL PRAYER.
WE'LL BE HEARING FROM THE
METHODIST CHURCH.
ECUMENICAL CHAPLAIN OF THE
LUTHERAN HOME OF SOUTHBURY.
ALL OF THESE FAITHS WILL BE
HERE.
THEY WILL TRY TO GIVE SOME
COMFORT TO THOSE WHO ARE
MOURNING.
SANJAY, AS WE WAIT FOR THE
START, THE FORMAL START AND THE
REVEREND MATTHEW CREBBIN, WE
LOOK AT THE PICTURES OF THIS
COMMUNITY, IT'S A SMALL
COMMUNITY THAT'S BEEN REALLY, I
THINK, SO POWERFUL DEVASTATED BY
WHAT HAS HAPPENED.
>> AND SOME OF THESE PEOPLE,
WOLF, SEEING EACH OTHER FOR THE
FIRST TIME SINCE ALL OF THIS
HAPPENED.
YOU SAW SOME OF THE IMAGES AS
PEOPLE WERE WALKING IN, AND
THOSE HUGS JUST TOLD A LOT.
THE LOOKS IN THE FACES.
WE SAW THE FIRST RESPONDERS COME
IN, AND WE HADN'T TALKED ABOUT
THE IMPACT ON THEM AS MUCH, BUT
THEY GOT A STANDING OVATION,
WOLF, AND I THINK EVEN THEM
TALKING TO EACH OTHER, THEY
OFTEN TIMES DON'T HAVE TIME TO
REFLECT ON WHAT HAS HAPPENED AND
THEY MAY NOT GET MUCH TIME EVEN
NOW, BUT CLEARLY THE SMALL TOWN
WHERE KIDS -- WHERE PARENTS
RAISE EACH OTHER'S KIDS, YOU'RE
SEEING IT HERE.
YOU'RE SEEING THEM COME TOGETHER
AND YOU'RE SEEING INSIDE THE
ROOM HERE, WOLF, AS YOU POINTED
OUT, THERE IS AN OVERFLOW ROOM.
THERE ARE PEOPLE OUTSIDE.
THERE ARE VILLAGE JIGILS ALL AR.
>> A LOT OF THESE PEOPLE HAVE
BROUGHT THEIR CHILDREN WITH THEM
TO THIS MEMORIAL SERVICE.
THESE ARE MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS
OUTSIDE RIGHT DOWN THE STREET
FROM WHERE WE WERE.
PEOPLE JUST BRINGING CANDLES AND
FLOWERS AND TOYS, AND NOW THE
PRESIDENT.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>>> ON BEHALF OF THE NEWTOWN
INTERFAITH CLERGY ASSOCIATION, I
WELCOME ALL OF YOU.
WE NEEDED THIS.
WE NEEDED TO BE TOGETHER HERE IN
THIS ROOM, IN THE
GYMNASIUM, OUTSIDE THE DOORS OF
THIS SCHOOL, IN LIVING ROOMS
AROUND THE WORLD.
WE NEEDED TO BE TOGETHER.
TO SHOW THAT WE ARE TOGETHER.
AND UNITED.
WE GATHER IN SUCH A MOMENT OF
HEART BREAK FOR ALL OF US HERE
IN NEWTOWN.
WE GATHER ESPECIALLY MINDFUL OF
FAMILY AND FRIENDS AND NEIGHBORS
AMONG US WHO HAVE LOST LOVED
ONES BY AN ACT OF UNFATHOMABLE
VIOLENCE AND DESTRUCTION.
WE GATHER TO GRIEVE TOGETHER, TO
CARE FOR ONE ANOTHER, TO PRAY
AND EMBRACE, TO WEEP AND TO
REMEMBER AND TO DECLARE IN OUR
MANY VOICES THAT THESE DARKEST
DAYS OF OUR COMMUNITY SHALL NOT
BE THE FINAL WORD HEARD FROM US.
WE WILL SIGH IN OUR SORROWS, BUT
WE WILL ALSO CARE FOR ONE
ANOTHER WITH OUR LOVE AND OUR
COMPASSION.
IN THOSE EARLY HOURS OF THIS
CRISIS, IT BECAME CLEAR TO WE
CLERGY AND FAITH LEADERS HERE IN
NEWTOWN THAT AN INITIAL
COMMUNITY RESPONSE WOULD BE
NEEDED, THAT WE WOULD NEED TO
COME TOGETHER, AND SO WE ASKED
OUR FIRST SELECT WOMAN AND OUR
SUPERINTENDENT IF IT MIGHT BE
POSSIBLE FOR US CLERGY TO INVITE
THE COMMUNITY TO GATHER HERE AT
NEWTOWN HIGH SCHOOL TO CONTINUE
AND TO BEGIN AND TO CONTINUE
WHAT WILL BE, FOR MANY, A LONG
JOURNEY THROUGH GRIEF AND LOSS.
WE ARE NOT HERE TO IGNORE OUR
DIFFERENCES OR TO DIMINISH OUR
CORE BELIEFS WHICH DEFINE OUR
MANY DIFFERENT FAITH TRADITIONS,
BUT TO OFFER OUR LOVE, CARE, AND
PRAYERS FOR OUR FAMILIES AND OUR
COMMUNITY.
WE WANTED TO OFFER OUR VOICES IN
THE FORM OF WORDS FROM OUR
SACRED TEXTS AND PRAYERS FROM
THE DEPTHS OF OUR BEING, BUT
ALSO TO HAVE TIME FOR US TO BE
TOGETHER IN SILENCE.
AND THAT IS WHAT WE WILL DO.
WE WILL HAVE A TIME FOR SHARING
AND PRAYER AND ALSO A TIME FOR
SILENCE IN BETWEEN SO THAT ALL
OF US CAN PRAY AS WE WISH AND
THINK ABOUT WHAT IT IS THAT IS
MOST IMPORTANT TO US.
NOW THERE'S A REASON WHY ALL OF
THE CLERGY ARE SITTING DOWN
THERE AND NOT UP HERE, AND WE
HOPE YOU DON'T GET TIRED OF
SEEING US HAVE A LONG WALK UP TO
THIS PODIUM.
BUT WE WANTED TO BE -- TO HAVE A
SYMBOLIC GESTURE THAT WE
OURSELVES ARE WITH YOU AND AMONG
YOU IN THESE COMING DAYS.
THAT WE ARE ALL IN THIS
TOGETHER.
WE WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT OUR
CARE FOR THIS COMMUNITY EXTENDS
BEYOND THE WALLS OF OUR VARIOUS
HOUSES OF WORSHIP AND THE PEOPLE
WITHIN THEM.
WE ARE HERE FOR ALL OF NEWTOWN.
THAT MEANS THAT YOU WHO ARE OF
ST. ROSE CATHOLIC CHURCH, IN THE
MIDST OF YOUR TREMENDOUS GRIEF,
THERE IS A JEWISH RABBI WITH A
TORAH IN HAND READY TO SPEAK
WORDS OF COMFORT AND DO WHATEVER
HE CAN TO UPHOLD YOU IN THE
COMING DAYS.
AND TEMPLE OF ISRAEL, YOU HAVE
THE SERVICE OF A
JAPANESE-AMERICAN UNITED
METHODIST MINISTER READY TO PRAY
FOR YOU AND SING SONGS FROM JOHN
WESLEY.
WE CONGREGATIONISTS KNOW WE HAVE
MUSLIM BROTHERS AND SISTERS
READY TO OFFER PRAYERS OF
COMFORT AND ACTS OF COMPASSION.
PENTECOSTAL IS WILLING TO PRAY
WITH EPISCOPALIANS, INDEPENDENT
CHRISTIANS, AND TO OTHERS.
AND ALL OF US WILLING TO OFFER
AND RECEIVE COMFORT AND SUPPORT
FROM THOSE OF NO FAITH.
YOU SEE, NOW MORE THAN EVER WE
NEED EACH OTHER, FOR WE ARE ALL
IN THIS TOGETHER.
THAT'S WHY WE EVEN HAD OUR
POLITICIANS SIT DOWN THERE AS
WELL.
AS SIGN AND SYMBOL AND REMINDER
TO ALL OF US THAT WE ARE IN THIS
TOGETHER.
SO NOW LET US COME TOGETHER.
LET US PRAY.
LET US LISTEN AND LET US SEEK
THE COMFORT OF OUR VARIOUS
FAITHS, DRAWING FROM WORDS AND
PRAYERS.
FEAR NOT FOR I AM WITH YOU.
BE NOT DISMAYED, FOR I AM YOUR
GOD.
I WILL STRENGTHEN YOU, I WILL
UPHOLD YOU WITH MY VICTORIOUS
HAND.
GOD IS WITH US.
GOD'S LOVE UNITES US, GOD'S
PURPOSE STEADIES US.
GOD'S SPIRIT COMFORTS US.
BLESS BE OUR GOD FOREVER AND
EVER.
AMEN.
>> I OFFER YOU THIS PRAYER FROM
MY HEART TO YOUR HEARTS.
ON BEHALF OF ALL OF YOUR
CHILDR
CHILDREN, ALL OF YOUR LOVED
ONES.
THE HEBREW MEMORIAL PRAYER.
PLEASE RISE.
♪