IS SUGGESTING A BAN ON ALL GUNS
IN AMERICA.
THE SECOND AMENDMENT IS
ABSOLUTELY PART OF AMERICAN
CULTURE AND PEOPLE BELIEVE IN
IT.
HOWEVER, THERE ARE LIMITATIONS.
THE AMENDMENT TALKS ABOUT A
WELL-REGULATED MILITIA.
PEOPLE ARE CALLING OUT FOR
TAKING SOME OF THESE WEAPONS
AWAY FROM PEOPLE WITH POTENTIAL
MENTAL ISSUES.
TO ME, THE QUESTION FOR YOU IS
THIS, THE LAST THREE MASS
SHOOTINGS IN THE LAST FOUR
MONTHS IN AMERICA, AURORA, OREGO
IN THE SHOPPING MALL AND NOW
HERE IN NEWTOWN HAVE INVOLVED
YOUNG PEOPLE USING THE SAME  AND
NOW HERE, NEWTOWN, ALL INVOLVED
YOUNG PEOPLE USING THE SAME
WEAPON.
AN AR-15 SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE ALL
WITH HIGH CAPACITY MAGAZINES.
IN AURORA, OVER 100 IN HIS
MAGAZINE WHICH HE COULD FIRE
OFF.
HERE WE SAW UP TO 30.
HERE'S THE QUESTION.
WHY DO YOU FEEL THAT AMERICANS
SHOULD HAVE THOSE IF YOUR BELIEF
IS THEY JUST HAVE TO DEFEND
THEMSELVES?
>> WELL, BEFORE I GO ANY
FURTHER, PIERS, FIRST, THANKS
FOR HAVING ME BACK.
WE DID HAVE A HEATED DISCUSSION
LAST TIME AND I MUCH APPRECIATE
THIS MORE CALM DISCUSSION.
SECOND, ON BEHALF OF I'M SURE I
SPEAK FOR THE ENTIRE BOARD OF
MICHIGAN COALITION OF
RESPONSIBLE GUN OWNERS WE OFFER
OUR SINCERE CONDOLENCE AND
SYMPATHIES FOR THE VICTIMS AND
THEIR FAMILIES.
WE ARE ALL ABOUT SAFETY.
WE ALL WANT TO BE SAFE AND WE
CERTAINLY WANT CHILDREN TO BE
SAFE.
LIKE I SAID LAST WEEK, WE JUST
DISAGREE ON HOW TO GET THERE
FROM HERE.
TO ANSWER YOUR QUESTION, I WOULD
POINT OUT THAT THE SHOOTER IN
THE MALL IN OREGON WAS
CONFRONTED BY A LEGALLY ARMED
CITIZEN WHO POINTED HIS GUN AT
THE SHOOTER AND THEN DECIDED NOT
TO SQUEEZE THE TRIGGER BECAUSE
HE WAS AFRAID OF MISSING AND
HITTING BYSTANDERS.
HE WAS ACTING VERY RESPONSIBLY.
AND THE NEXT SHOT THAT THAT
SHOOTER FIRED, THAT THE KILLER
FIRED, WAS ON HIMSELF AFTER HE
WAS CONFRONTED WITH AN ARMED
CITIZEN.
SO THAT'S ACTUALLY ONE EXAMPLE
OF A RESPONSIBLE GUN OWNER USING
A GUN TO SAVE LIVES.
>> WELL, HE ACTUALLY DIDN'T USE
THE GUN.
I THINK THE POINT, DAN, UNLESS
I'M MISTAKEN.
YOU TAKE IT UP HERE.
BUT I DON'T THINK ANY AMERICAN
CITIZEN WITH A LEGAL GUN HAS
EVER INTERVENED IN A MASS
SHOOTING, CERTAINLY NOT IN THE
LAST 30 OR 40 YEARS IN AMERICA.
SO IT SEEMS TO BE A BIT OF A
MYTH --
>> ACTUALLY, THEY HAVE.
>> LET DAN ANSWER.
>> BEFORE THIS EVOLVES INTO AN
ARGUMENT, I MEAN, AS EASY AS IT
IS TO BECOME UNINSPIRED BY A
CONVERSATION LIKE THIS AND WHAT
YOUR OTHER GUEST IS SAYING, I
JUST ENCOURAGE THE AMERICAN
PUBLIC TO NOT LOSE THE SENSE OF
INSPIRATION IN TERMS OF THE
CHANGE THAT WE HAVE THE
POTENTIAL TO ACCOMPLISH.
THIS IS NOT THE CONVERSATION
THAT THE AMERICAN PUBLIC WANT TO
HAVE.
THIS IS NOT OUR VISION WHERE THE
ANSWER TO VIOLENCE IS MORE
VIOLENCE, WHERE THE ANSWER TO
GUNS IS MORE GUNS.
THERE IS FERTILE GROUND WHERE
THE OVERWHELMING MAJORITY OF
AMERICANS AGREE WITH THINGS LIKE
BACKGROUND CHECKS TO MAKE SURE
THAT 40% OF ALL GUN SALES THAT
ARE NOT CURRENTLY COVERED BY
BACKGROUND CHECKS TO PREVENT
MENTALLY ILL PEOPLE FROM GETTING
GUNS, TO PREVENT CRIMINALS AND
DOMESTIC ABUSERS FROM GETTING
GUNS, TO CLOSE THAT GAPING HOLE
IN OUR SYSTEM.
GUN OWNERS, 74% OF NRA MEMBERS
SUPPORT SOLUTIONS LIKE THAT.
UNFORTUNATELY, SOMETIMES THIS
PLAYS OUT AS A POLARIZED
POLITICAL DEBATE IN SEGMENTS
LIKE THE ONE I WAS PART OF ALSO
ON FRIDAY NIGHT, BUT THE REALITY
IS THE AMERICAN PUBLIC ISN'T
POLARIZED.
THE ONLY PLACE THIS IS A
POLARIZED POLITICAL DEBATE IS IN
CONGRESS.
WHAT WE NEED TO DO IS WE NEED TO
TAKE THE VOICE OF THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE WHO KNOW THAT,
AS PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID TONIGHT,
WE CAN BE BETTER THAN THIS AND
HOLD OUR LEADERS ACCOUNTABLE.
>> TO THE POLITICS SIDE, THIS IS
VERY INTERESTING TO ME.
THIS IS ALMOST A MIRROR TRAGEDY
OF WHAT HAPPENED IN BRITAIN IN
1996 AND SCOTLAND, 16 YOUNG 5
AND 6-YEAR-OLD CHILDREN WERE
KILLED.
IT WAS THE WORST SHOOTING OF ITS
TYPE IN MODERN AMERICAN HISTORY,
AND AS A RESULT, A FULL HANDGUN
BAN WAS BROUGHT IN.
WHICH WOULD NOT BE APPLICABLE
HERE, BECAUSE THERE ARE TOO MANY
IN CIRCULATION, HOWEVER, IT DID
HAPPEN.
BUT WHAT WAS MOST NOTABLE ABOUT
THE DEBATE, IT WAS COMPLETELY
NON-POLITICAL.
IT NEVER DESCENDED INTO LEFT AND
RIGHT.
MY QUESTION FOR YOU, STEVE, IS
WHY DOES THIS HAVE TO BE
POLITICAL?
WHY CAN IT NOT JUST BE A
BIPARTISAN, ALL ENCOMPASSING,
AMERICAN DIALOGUE, WHICH LEADS
IN THE END TO PRAGMATIC
SOLUTION?
>> I AGREE WITH YOUR LAST
STATEMENT, ABSOLUTELY, PIERS.
IN FACT, OUR GROUP IS A SINGLE
ISSUE NON-PARTISAN GROUP.
WE HAVE INDEPENDENTS, DEMOCRATS,
AND REPUBLICANS ON OUR BOARD AND
IN OUR MEMBERSHIP, AND MOST ARE
ELECTED OFFICIALS.
WE ACTUALLY DO TAKE THAT
POSITION.
>> DO YOU AGREE WITH UNIVERSAL
BACKGROUND CHECKS?
>> UNIVERSAL BACKGROUND CHECKS?
>> YES.
>> YOU KNOW WE HAVE THE CRIMINAL
BACKGROUND CHECK IN PLACE.
>> RIGHT, BUT THAT ONLY APPLIES
TO 60% OF GUN SALES.
DO YOU AGREE WITH COVERING THE
OTHER 40% OF GUN SALES WITH
BACKGROUND CHECKS?
>> WE AGREE THAT DISQUALIFIED
INDIVIDUALS SHOULD NOT HAVE
ACCESS TO FIREARMS.
>> SO YOU AGREE WITH THE
BACKGROUND CHECKS THAT WOULD
BE --
>> ARE YOU GOING TO LET ME
FINISH?
PLEASE, PLEASE.
>> LET ME ASK YOU, GIVE ME ONE
GOOD REASON WHY THERE SHOULDN'T
BE 100% BACKGROUND CHECKS ON ALL
GUN TRANSACTIONS IN AMERICA.
GIVE ME A GOOD REASON.
>> IT'S LITERALLY IMPOSSIBLE,
PIERS, AS YOU POINTED OUT A
MOMENT AGO, TO DO 100%.
WE HAVE A LOT OF GUNS IN
CIRCULATION ON EARTH AND IN THE
UNITED STATES.
WE KNOW THAT GUNS PASS ACROSS
BORDERS.
>> WE'RE TALKING ABOUT NEW ONES.
>> NATIONAL AND STATE BORDERS.
>> LET ME FOCUS THE QUESTION
MORE SOLIDLY AND REALISTICALLY.
NEW GUNS PURCHASED FROM THIS DAY
FORWARD, WOULD YOU BE SUPPORTIVE
OF 100% REGISTRATION,
ACCOUNTABILITY, DATABASE, A
NATIONAL DATABASE, AND IF YOU'RE
NOT IN FAVOR OF THAT, WHY
WOULDN'T YOU BE?
>> OR AS CLOSE AS WE CAN GET TO
100%, WHICH IS A LOT CLOSER THAN
WHERE WE ARE NOW.
>> THE SYSTEM WE HAVE IN PLACE
RIGHT NOW IS A LIST OF THOSE
DISQUALIFIED.
PERSONALLY, I WOULD SUPPORT THAT
BASED ON EVERYTHING I'VE BEEN
ABLE TO LEARN IN MY POSITION AS
PROFESSOR OF FIREARMS LAW AND IN
MY POSITION AS A TRAINER OF
CONCEALED PISTOL LICENSEES THAT
THE NATIONAL INSTANT CHECK
SYSTEM SEEMS TO BE WORKING QUITE
WELL.
I BELIEVE THAT'S ONE AREA
EVERYONE AGREES.
>> WE SHOULD APPLY TO 100% OF
GUN SALES?
>> WE HAVE A LIST OF FOLKS WHO
ARE DISQUALIFIED WHO HAVE BEEN
ADJUDICATED MENTALLY ILL, FELONY
RECORDS THAT DISQUALIFY THEM, ET
CETERA.
THAT SYSTEM SEEMS TO WORK QUITE
WELL.
>> WE HAVE TO WRAP IT UP.
FINAL QUESTION FOR YOU, STEVE,
IS THIS.
IN LIGHT OF THE FACT THE LAST
THREE MASS SHOOTINGS, AS I SAID,
ALL FEATURED AN AR-15 RIFLE
AIDED AND ABETTED BY
HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINES, GIVE ME
A GOOD REASON WHY YOU ARE
COMFORTABLE WITH THOSE WEAPONS
STILL BEING SOLD IN CONNECTION
WITH HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINES IN
AMERICA IN PLACES LIKE WALMART?
>> FAIR ENOUGH.
AND I DON'T KNOW ANY PARTICULAR
RETAILER, BUT I WILL SAY WE DID
TRY FROM 1994 TO 2004, WE TRIED
THE SO-CALLED ASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN.
IT HAD NO IMPACT ON CRIME THAT
ANYONE COULD MEASURE WHATSOEVER,
AND THE TRUTH IS SOMETIMES THESE
GUNS ARE USED IN VERY POSITIVE
WAYS TO SAVE LIVES.
THEY ARE FUNCTIONALLY IDENTICAL
TO SEMI-AUTOMATIC WEAPONS THAT
DATE BACK LITERALLY TO THE
1800s.
A HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINE IS
NOTHING BUT A STEEL BOX AND A
SPRING.
IT'S INCREDIBLY EASY TO MAKE A
HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINE.
THE TRUTH IS THAT ANY SUCH BAN
WOULD BE INEFFECTIVE.
>> THIS IS TOTALLY DISCONNECTED
WITH WHAT THE AMERICAN PEOPLE
WANT AND THE CONVERSATION THAT'S
HAPPENING OUT THERE, AND THAT'S
WHAT GIVES ME INSPIRATION TO
CONTINUE TO HAVE CONVERSATIONS
LIKE THIS.
THE AMERICAN PUBLIC KNOWS WE ARE
BETTER THAN THIS.
WE DON'T WANT TO LIVE IN A
SOCIETY WHERE VIOLENCE LEADS TO
MORE VIOLENCE AND GUNS LEAD TO
MORE GUNS.
THAT'S THE CONVERSATION
THAT'S STARTING.
THAT'S THE CONVERSATION THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS LEADING AND
THAT THE AMERICAN PEOPLE NEED TO
SPEAK UP AROUND.
>> GOT TO LEAVE IT THERE.
>> WE ALL AGREE WE NEED SAFETY.
>> WE'RE ALL AGREED ON THAT.
I'M SURE THIS DEBATE WILL
CONTINUE.
WE WILL CONTINUE THIS DEBATE ON
THE SHOW.
IT'S BEEN AN IMPORTANT ONE FOR
AMERICA.
THANK YOU BOTH.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID WE
CAN'T TOLERATE THIS ANYMORE, BUT
WILL THERE BE A CHANGE IN
GUN POLICY?
I'LL ASK FRANK BRUNI AFTER THE
BREAK.
>>> I WISH TO GOD SHE HAD HAD AN
M4 IN HER OFFICE LOCKED UP SO
WHEN SHE HEARD GUNFIRE SHE PULLS
IT OUT AND SHE DIDN'T HAVE TO
LUNGE HEROICALLY WITH NOTHING IN
HER HANDS, BUT SHE TAKES HIM
OFF, TAKES HIS HEAD OFF BEFORE
HE COULD KILL THOSE PRECIOUS
KIDS.
>> TEXAS CONGRESSMAN SAYING
SOMETHING MANY AMERICANS AGREE
WITH.
BUT IS ARMING TEACHERS A
SOLUTION?
FRANK BRUNI, WHEN I HEAR THAT, I
JUST DESPAIR, BUT IT IS A VIEW
MANY AMERICANS HAVE.
POLLS SUGGEST THAT IF THE
TEACHERS HAD ALL BEEN ARMED, ONE
WOULD HAVE SHOT THIS GUY AND
CHILDREN'S LIVES WOULD HAVE BEEN
SAVED.
>> IF POLICE OFFICERS CAN'T FIRE
WITH AN ACCURACY, THEY CAN'T
PREVENT THEMSELVES FROM INJURING
THOSE PEOPLE.
WHY WOULD WE BELIEVE TEACHERS IN
SCHOOLS WOULD HAVE WONDERFUL
MARKSMANSHIP AND WOULD MAKE THIS
A BETTER THING.
IT DEFIES COMMON SENSE.
>> I THINK IT'S RIDICULOUS.
IT CANNOT BE TRUE.
AMERICA HAS THE MOST GUNS OF ANY
OF THE CIVILIZED WORLD.
>> AND THE MOST GUN RELATED
DEATHS.
>> TWICE AS MANY AS ANYBODY
ELSE.
>> RIGHT, RIGHT.
>> THE PENNY DOESN'T SEEM TO
DROP WITH PEOPLE.
>> YOU HAD DAN GROSS ON BEFORE.
I MET HIM BACK IN 1997 WHEN
ANOTHER EMPIRE STATE SHOOTING UP
AT THE TOP, HIS BROTHER WAS
HORRIBLY, HORRIBLY INJURED.
I'VE BEEN WRITING ON AND OFF
ABOUT GUN CONTROL.
SINCE THEN 15 YEARS, STATES HAVE
GOTTEN MORE LAX.
THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT HAS DONE
ANYTHING.
WE'RE GOING TO SEE WHAT WE'RE
MADE OF.
I FEEL LIKE THERE'S A DEGREE OF
HEARTBREAK AND LEVEL OF OUTRAGE
THAT IS BIGGER THAN I'VE EVER
SEEN.
WE'RE GOING TO FIND OUT WHETHER
WE'RE WILLING TO DO ANYTHING.
>> I COMPLETELY AGREE.
I THINK PRESIDENT OBAMA IS
EMOTIONAL NOW, HE SAID THIS IS
THE FOURTH TIME TO COMFORT
COMMUNITIES TORN APART BY
SHOOTINGS.
SIX OF THE WORST MASS SHOOTINGS
IN AMERICAN HISTORY HAVE
HAPPENED SINCE 2007.
THIS IS BORDERING ON AN
EPIDEMIC.
>> IT'S NOT BORDERING ANYMORE.
IT IS AN EPIDEMIC.
I THINK SOMETHING WILL CHANGE.
FOR THE FIRST TIME OUT OF THIS
MISERY I FEEL A LITTLE BIT OF
HOPE.
I WATCHED YOUR SHOW FRIDAY, THE
AMOUNT OF OUTRAGE IN YOUR VOICE
WAS HIGHER THAN I HAD EVER SEEN.
I THINK ABOUT THE OPENING OF
"SATURDAY NIGHT LIVE" LAST NIGHT
WITH THAT RENDITION OF "SIDELINE
THE NIGHT."
I WATCHED THE PRESIDENT ON
TELEVISION LAST NIGHT.
IT FEELS LIKE PEOPLE HAVE HAD
ENOUGH.
THE PRESIDENT SAID CAUSES ARE
COMPLEX AND WE DON'T KNOW BUT HE
SAID WE HAVE AN OBLIGATION TO
TRY.
AND I THINK THOSE WERE KEY
WORDS.
I THINK WE ALL FINALLY REALIZE
WHETHER SOMETHING'S GOING TO
WORK OR NOT, WE CAN'T JUST SAY
OH, THE ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN
DIDN'T WORK SO WELL.
WE HAVE AN OBLIGATION TO TRIAL.
THERE ARE ALL OF THESE DEAD
CHILDREN THAT ARE NOT GOING TO
LIVE TO SEE TOMORROW.
WE OWE OUR BEST EFFORT, EVEN IF
IT'S A FLAWED EFFORT.
>> THERE HAS TO BE A BETTER
SYSTEM.
ON GUNS, IT HAS TO BE A SPECIFIC
DEBATE.
IT'S NO GOOD SAYING BAN GUNS.
IT'S NEVER GOING TO HAPPEN IN
AMERICA AND THERE'S TOO MANY OUT
THERE.
THE ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN, I DON'T
BELIEVE IT WAS AS INEFFECTUAL AS
THEY WOULD LIKE US TO HAVE US
BELIEVE.
ALLOWING THEM TO COME BACK IN,
WHY DOES ANY YOUNG MAN IN
AMERICA OR WOMAN, THEY'RE ALL
MEN AT THE MOMENT, NEED ONE OF
THESE AR-15 ASSAULT RIFLES
CAPABLE OF FIRING HUNDREDS OF
BULLETS.
>> OR THE HIGH CAPACITY CLIPS.
WHAT ABOUT THE SECOND AMENDMENT
SAYS TO US PEOPLE HAS TO HAVE
ACCESS TO THOSE?
WE CAN'T OUTLAW THEM, PUT
STRINGENT REQUIREMENTS.
IT DOESN'T MEAN WE'LL BE ABLE TO
ENFORCE IT PERFECTLY.
EVEN IF WE ENFORCE IT IN A
FLAWED FASHION THAT PREVENTS ONE
MASSACRE OR FIVE DEATHS A YEAR,
DON'T WE OWE IT TO THE COUNTRY
AND THE CHILDREN OF COUNTRY TO
TRY THAT?
>> DO YOU THINK THE SCALE OF
WHAT HAPPENED IN NEWTOWN MAKES
THIS THE TIPPING POINT.
>> I THINK WHAT MAKES IT A
TIPPING POINT IS WHERE IT COMES
IN THE SEQUENCE AND THE AGE OF
THE VICTIMS.
WHEN YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT KIDS
THIS AGE, I THINK THAT'S WHAT
REALLY GOT TO PEOPLE.
>> FRANK, GOOD TO SEE YOU.
>> GOOD TO SEE YOU.
>> AFTER THE BREAK WE'LL
REMEMBER THOSE VICTIMS IN
SILENCE, EACH OF THEM, BY NAME
AND BY PICTURE.
[ children laughing ]
MOVE TO THE COUNTRY,
AND LIVE A LONG, HAPPY LIFE
TOGETHER
WHERE THEY ALMOST NEVER FIGHT
ABOUT MONEY.
[ dog barks ]
BECAUSE RIGHT AFTER
THEY GET MARRIED,
THEY'LL FIND
SOME RETIREMENT PEOPLE
WHO ARE PAID ON SALARY,
NOT COMMISSION.
THEY'LL GET
STRAIGHTFORWARD GUIDANCE
AND BE ABLE TO FOCUS ON OTHER
THINGS, LIKE EACH OTHER,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
>>> WE LEAVE YOU TONIGHT WITH
THE NAMES AND PHOTOGRAPHS OF THE
VICTIMS OF THE SANDY HOOK
TRAGEDY.
20 CHILDREN AND 6 TEACHERS WHO
MUST NEVER BE FORGOTTEN.
HERE THEY ARE.
>>> THE END OF THE MOST
HARROWING WEEKEND IMAGINABLE FOR
THIS TOWN OR ANY TOWN.
SADLY, THE DAYS AHEAD WON'T GET
BETTER.
THERE ARE MANY DIFFICULT DAYS
AND MONTHS AND WEEKS AHEAD.
STARTING TOMORROW, PARENTS WILL
BEGIN BURYING THEIR CHILDREN,
TRYING TO IMAGINE IT IS ALMOST
UNTHINKABLE.
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO FIND THE
WORDS, ALL THE WORDS THAT WE CAN
SAY IN THIS HOUR ARE GOING TO
SEEM SO SMALL IN THE FACE OF THE
TRAGEDY THAT HAS OCCURRED HERE.
NOW IS THE TIME TO LEAN ON ONE
ANOTHER OR THE PARENTS AND THE
LOVED ONES AND THE FAMILIES HERE
CAN TO BE THE ONE TO LEAN ON.
THEY CAME TOGETHER TONIGHT FOR A
VIGIL, CROWDING INTO THE LOCAL
HIGH SCHOOL JUST BEHIND ME.
THE LOCAL HIGH SCHOOL AUDITORIUM
TO LISTEN TO SPIRITUAL LEADERS
OFFERED WORDS OF COMFORT.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SPOKE AS WELL.
SAYING WE AS A NATION ARE SIMPLY
NOT DOING ENOUGH TO KEEP OUR
CHILDREN SAFE.
HE PROMISED TO WORK TO PUT AN
END TO FUTURE TRAGEDIES LIKE
THIS ONE.
WE'LL PLAY YOU HIS CALL FOR
ACTION SHORTLY.
BUT WE DON'T WANT TO FOCUS ON
THE KILLER.
FOR THE LAST SEVERAL DAYS WE
HAVEN'T SAID HIS NAME AND I
DON'T WANT HISTORY TO REMEMBER
HIM.
WE AND THE PEOPLE HERE WANT
HISTORY TO REMEMBER THE TEACHERS
AND THE CHILDREN AND THOSE WHOSE
LIVES HAVE BEEN SO UNFORTUNATELY
TAKEN.
PEOPLE WITH HOPES AND WITH
DREAMS AND WITH STORIES.
EVEN THOUGH 20 OF THOSE STORIES
HAD ONLY JUST BEGUN.
WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THEIR
LIVES FROM PARENTS AND FROM
FRIENDS AND LOCAL AND NATIONAL
PAPERS AND FROM LOCAL BLOGS.
IF YOU REMEMBER AFTER THE
SHOOTING IN AURORA THERE WAS A
VIGIL IN AURORA, COLORADO AND
EVERY TIME SOMEBODY'S NAME WAS
READ, ONE OF THE VICTIM'S NAME
WAS READ, THE CROWD SAID BACK WE
WILL REMEMBER.
AND SO WITH THAT IN MIND
TONIGHT, I THOUGHT WE'D TAKE A
FEW MOMENTS TO READ YOU THE
NAMES OF EACH AND EVERY FALLEN
CHILD AND GROWN-UP AND TELL YOU
WHAT WE CAN ABOUT THEIR LIVES.
CHARLOTTE BACON.
WAS 6 YEARS OLD.
WE WILL REMEMBER HER.
SHE WAS WEARING A NEW PINK DRESS
AND BOOTS, A HOLIDAY OUTFIT.
CHARLOTTE BEGGED HER MOM TO WEAR
IT TO SCHOOL THAT DAY.
HER BIG BROTHER WAS ALSO AT
SCHOOL THAT DAY BUT WE'RE TOLD
HE MADE IT TO SAFETY.
HER UNCLE SAYS SHE COULD LIGHT
UP A ROOM.
WE'LL ALSO REMEMBER DANIEL
BARDEN, 7 YEARS OLD, JUST 7
YEARS OLD, DANIEL WAS A BUDDING
ATHLETE.
HE SWAM, PLAYED SOCCER, WAS
MISSING TWO FRONT TEETH.
HIS FAMILY CALLED HIM FEARLESS.
WE WILL REMEMBER OLIVIA ENGEL AS
WELL, JUST 6 YEARS OLD.
SHE PLAYED TENNIS AND SOCCER,
WAS A BALLET DANCER AND A
PATIENT BIG SISTER TO HER
3-YEAR-OLD BROTHER.
HER FAMILY SAID SHE LOVED
SCHOOL, COLORS, PINK AND PURPLE
AND WAS GOING TO BE AN ANGEL IN
A NATIVITY PLAY SCHEDULE FOR
JUST LAST NIGHT.
WE WILL REMEMBER 7-YEAR-OLD
JOSEPHINE GAY AS WELL.
JOSEPHINE TURNED 7 ON TUESDAY.
SHE, TOO, LOVED THE COLOR
PURPLE, HER NEIGHBORS ARE
HANGING PURPLE BALLOONS FROM
MAILBOXES AND FENCES IN HER
MEMORY.
WE WILL REMEMBER HER.
WE'LL ALSO REMEMBER ANA
MARQUEZ-GREENE, 6 YEARS OLD, ANA
GREW UP WITH MUSIC IN HER EARS.
HER DAD PLAYS JAZZ, SAXOPHONE
AND FLUTE.
HIS 2009 ALBUM FEATURES A SONG
HE WROTE ABOUT HER, THE TITLE
"ANA GRACE."
WE'LL ALSO REMEMBER DIYLAN
HOCKLEY.
HE TOO, 6 YEARS OLD.
HE CAME FROM ENGLAND ORIGINALLY.
HIS MOM RECENTLY CALLING THE
AREA A WONDERFUL PLACE TO LIVE
WITH INCREDIBLE NEIGHBORS AND
WONDERFUL SCHOOLS.
WE WILL REMEMBER DYLAN.
WE'LL ALSO REMEMBER 6-YEAR-OLD
MADELEINE HSU.
MADDIE THEY CALL HER.
SHE WAS UPBEAT AND KIND, A SWEET
AND WONDERFUL LITTLE GIRL.
WE'RE REMEMBER ALSO KATHERICATH
HUBBARD.
SHE LOVED ANIMALS.
HER FAMILY IS REQUESTING
DONATIONS BE MADE TO THE NEWTOWN
ANIMAL SHELTER SAYING THAT'S
PROBABLY WHAT SHE WOULD HAVE
WANTED.
WE'LL REMEMBER HER.
WE'LL REMEMBER 7-YEAR-OLD CHASE
KOWALSKI.
FOR HIS LOVE OF OUTDOOR SPORTS
AND HIS TALENT FOR THEM.
HE JUST WON HIS FIRST MINI
TRIATHLON.
A NEIGHBOR SAYS HE WAS ALWAYS
OUTSIDE RIDING HIS BIKE.
WE WILL REMEMBER CHASE KOWALSKI.
WE'LL REMEMBER THAT 6-YEAR-OLD
JESSE LEWIS WAS LEARNING HOW TO
RIDE A HORSE.
IT WAS ONLY NATURAL, HIS FAMILY
HAD FIVE OF THEM, TWO
MINIATURES, THREE DOGS, A FLOCK
OF CHICKENS.
HIS MOTHER SAID HE LOVED TO TELL
STORIES AND LIVED LIFE BRAVE AND
TRUE.
WE WILL REMEMBER.
WE'LL ALSO REMEMBER 6-YEAR-OLD
JAMES.
HE'S BEING REMEMBERED AS A
SWEETHEART OF A KID WITH SUCH AN
INNOCENT FACE.
A FACE THAT WE AND THEY AND
EVERYONE SHOULD REMEMBER.
WE'LL REMEMBER THE FACE OF
7-YEAR-OLD GRACE McDONNELL, A
NEIGHBOR DESCRIBES IT AS THE
FACE OF AN ANGEL.
SHE WAS HER MOTHER'S LITTLE BEST
FRIEND.
HER FAMILY IN A BRIEF STATEMENT
SAYING, OUR DAUGHTER GRACE WAS
THE LOVE AND LIGHT OF OUR
FAMILY.
WORDS CANNOT ADEQUATELY EXPRESS
OUR SENSE OF LOSS.
WE, TOO, WILL REMEMBER GRACE.
AND WE'LL ALSO REMEMBER EMILIE
PARKER, JUST 6 YEARS OLD, EMILIE
WAS A MENTOR TO HER TWO YOUNGER
SISTERS AGES 3 AND 4.
HER FATHER SAYS -- HER FATHER
SAID WHEN THEY NEEDED COMFORT
THEY LOOKED TO EMILIE.
THEY WILL REMEMBER HER AND SO
WILL WE.
WE'LL REMEMBER ANOTHER
6-YEAR-OLD, JACK PINTO, JACK
LOVED WRESTLING.
HE AND HIS TEAM WERE SCHEDULED
TO COMPETE THIS WEEKEND AT A
MATCH AGAINST A NEW JERSEY
WRESTLING CLUB.
WE WILL REMEMBER HIM.
THERE'S SO MANY FOLKS, SO MANY
PEOPLE TO REMEMBER, NOAH POZNER,
6 YEARS OLD, AS SMART AS A WHIP
ACCORDING TO HIS UNCLE WHO LOVED
READING AND FIGURING THINGS OUT,
NOAH'S TWIN SISTER WAS AT SCHOOL
AS WELL ON FRIDAY.
THE TWO WERE SAID TO BE
INSEPARABLE.
SHE SURVIVED.
HE DID NOT.
WHEN TALKING TO NOAH'S AUNT
LATER TONIGHT.
WE'LL REMEMBER HIM.
6-YEAR-OLD CAROLINE, KNOWN FOR A
TIME AS BOO BECAUSE SHE
RESEMBLED THE LITTLE GIRL IN
"MONSTER'S INC.
" WE WILL REMEMBER HER.
JESSICA.
SHE LOVED HORSES AND WANTED KOU
GIRL BOOTS FOR CHRISTMAS.
WE'LL REMEMBER AVIELLE RICHMAN.
SHE WAS EXCITED BECAUSE SHE WAS
ABOUT TO LOSE HER FIRST TOOTH.
BENJAMIN WHEELER'S BIRTH LED HIS
FAMILY TO NEWTOWN, THEY MOVED
OUT OF NEW YORK IN SEARCH OF
SOME PLACE QUIET.
BENJAMIN WAS ALSO 6 YEARS OLD
AND WE'LL REMEMBER HIM.
AND WE'LL REMEMBER ALLISON
WYATT, 6 YEARS OLD, NONE OF THE
CHILDREN WHO DIED WAS OLDER THAN
7.
WE'LL REMEMBER RACHEL DAVINO,
SHE WAS 29, DEVOTED TO HELPING
SPECIAL NEEDS CHILDREN.
52-YEAR-OLD ANNE MARIE MURPHY
HELPED SHIELD HER STUDENTS FROM
THE KILLER, THE GUNFIRE AND HAD
HER ARMS AROUND SOME OF THEM AT
THE END.
WE'LL REMEMBER HER AND SO WILL
THIS COMMUNITY.
WE'LL REMEMBER 30-YEAR-OLD
LAUR
LAUREN RUSSEAU.
SHE WAS A FULL-TIME SUBSTITUTE
AT SANDY HOOK.
WE'LL REMEMBER SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST, MARY SHERLACH.
WE'LL REMEMBER HER.
WE WILL ALSO REMEMBER VICTORIA
SOTO.
NO ONE IN THIS TOWN WILL EVER
FORGET 27-YEAR-OLD VICTORIA SOTO
WHO DIED TRYING TO PROTECT THE
LIVES OF HER FIRST GRADERS.
SHE WAS THE OLDEST OF FOUR
CHILDREN.
WE WILL REMEMBER HER AND, OF
COURSE, WE WILL REMEMBER THE
SCHOOL PRINCIPAL, DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG.
SHE WAS FIRM AND FUNNY AND THE
KIDS LOVED HER.
EVEN LITTLE KIDS KNOW WHEN
SOMEONE CARES ABOUT THEM.
THAT WAS HER AND WE'LL REMEMBER
HER.
JUST AS WE REMEMBER ALL 26 LIVES
LOST IN THAT SCHOOL ON THAT DAY,
26 STORIES CUT SHORT FRIDAY
MORNING HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
NEWTOWN IS NOW THE NATION'S
HEARTACHE.
IT IS OUR OPEN WOUND, A HOLE SO
LARGE SAID ONE MINISTER IN
PRAYER TONIGHT THAT WE'RE NOT
EVEN SURE GOD CAN FILL IT.
SOMETHING TO HOPE FOR AND TO HIS
HOPE AND HIS HOPE IS EVERYONE'S
HOPE AS WE BRING YOU MOMENTS
FROM TONIGHT'S VIGIL STARTING
WITH FIRST RESPONDERS COMING
INTO THE AUDITORIUM TO A ROUND
OF APPLAUSE.
♪
>> WE GATHER HERE IN MEMORY OF 0
BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN AND 6
REMARKABLE ADULTS THEY LOST
THEIR LIVS IN A SCHOOL THAT
COULD HAVE BEEN ANY SCHOOL.
IN A QUIET TOWN FULL OF GOD AND
DECENT PEOPLE THAT COULD BE ANY
TOWN IN AMERICA.
HERE IN NEWTOWN, I COME TO OFFER
THE LOVE AND PRAYERS OF A
NATION.
I AM VERY MINDFUL THAT MERE
WORDS CANNOT MATCH THE DEPTHS OF
YOUR SORROW.
NOR CAN THEY HEAL YOUR WOUNDED
HEARTS.
I CAN ONLY HOPE IT HELPS FOR YOU
TO KNOW THAT YOU'RE NOT ALONE IN
YOUR GRIEF, THAT OUR WORLD, TOO,
HAS BEEN TORN APART.
THAT ALL ACROSS THIS LAND OF
OURS, WE HAVE WEPT WITH YOU.
WE'VE PULLED OUR CHILDREN TIGHT.
AND YOU MUST KNOW THAT WHATEVER
MEASURE OF COMFORT WE CAN
PROVIDE, WE WILL PROVIDE.
>> WITH ME NOW ARE TWO CLERGY
MEMBERS WHO SPOKE AT THE VIGIL.
THE REVEREND MATT CREBBIN,
SENIOR MINISTER OF THE NEWTOWN
CONGREGATIONAL CHURCH.
AND RABBI PRAVER.
WHAT DO YOU WANT TO COME OUT OF
THIS?
WHAT DO YOU WANT PEOPLE TO KNOW?
>> I'M HOPING, ANDERSON, THIS
WILL BE THE TIPPING POINT IN OUR
COUNTRY.
I FEEL THAT CHILDREN ARE
INUNDATED WITH THE CULTURE OF
VIOLENCE FROM A VERY YOUNG AGE.
FROM THE TOYS THAT WE PLAY WITH
TO THE MOVIES THAT WE SEE AND
THE TV THAT WE SEE.
THAT WE CAN DO BETTER, AND WE
CAN MAKE GAMES THAT ARE EXCITING
THAT HAVE A POSITIVE OBJECTIVE.
AND WE REALLY NEED TO DO THAT,
BECAUSE I THINK IT'S TOO
COMMONPLACE, THE VIOLENT
REACTION.
OF COURSE, THE INDIVIDUAL IS
DERANGED BUT THERE'S A PART OF
ME THAT THINKS IF WE HAD MORE OF
A CULTURE OF PEACE THAT THESE
KIND OF EVENTS WOULD BE LESS
LIKELY TO HAPPEN.
>> REVEREND, WHAT ARE YOU HOPING
COMES OUT OF THIS?
>> WELL, I'M HOPING FOR OUR
COMMUNITY THAT THE COMMUNITY
GROWS EVEN CLOSER AND STRONGER.
I KNOW PEOPLE HAVE SPOKEN ABOUT
HOW CLOSE AND STRONG IT WAS
BEFORE.
BUT AS YOU KNOW, IN A TRAGEDY
LIKE THIS, WE'RE VERY
VULNERABLE.
BUT I ALSO HAVE HOPE THAT WE CAN
BECOME STRONGER AND CLOSER AND
CARE FOR ONE ANOTHER IN DEEPER
WAYS.
>> IT'S EXTRAORDINARY JUST THE
LAST COUPLE DAYS, I'VE BEEN
HERE.
COMPLETE STRANGERS COME UP TO
ONE ANOTHER ON THE STREET AND
ARE HUGGING AND SHARING, SHARING
THEIR HEARTS WITH EACH OTHER.
>> RIGHT.
AND THERE'S AN OUTPOURING, BOTH
IN THE TOWN BUT AS YOU WELL
KNOW, FROM PEOPLE AROUND THE
WORLD.
AND -- BUT THAT WILL SLOWLY
DISSIPATE.
AND THE ATTENTION WILL DISAPPEAR
FROM THIS PLACE, AND WE'LL BE
RETURNING TO LIVES THAT ARE
SUPPOSED TO BE NORMAL.
FOR MANY PEOPLE, THEY WON'T FEEL
NORMAL AGAIN.
HOW DO WE MAKE THOSE LIVES FEEL
CONNECTED AND CLOSER AND CARED
FOR AND VIBRANT?
BECAUSE WE DON'T WANT THIS EVENT
TO DEFINE THE SPIRIT OF OUR
FAITH COMMUNITIES, THE SPIRIT OF
THIS COMMUNITY.
WE WANT PEOPLE TO KNOW THAT
THERE IS SOMETHING MORE,
SOMETHING HOPEFUL, SOMETHING
THAT WE CAN EVEN BECOME MORE
COMPASSIONATE, MORE CARING, SOME
OF THE THINGS SHAUL HAS TALKED
ABOUT, HOW WE SEE PEOPLE NOT
JUST HERE IN FOUND BUT IN THE
WORLD.
>> I THOUGHT SEEING
REPRESENTATIVES FROM ALL FAITHS
W
ON THAT STAGE TONIGHT WAS A VERY
POWERFUL AND MOVING STATEMENT.
WHAT DO YOU -- HOW -- THERE'S SO
MANY PARENTS AROUND THE WORLD
WHO ARE FOLLOWING THIS, WHO
DON'T KNOW WHAT TO SAY TO THEIR
CHILDREN, DON'T KNOW HOW TO
EXPLAIN IT.
HOW DO YOU COUNCIL SOMEBODY.
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THEM?
>> YOU MEAN, AROUND THE COUNTRY?
>> YEAH, OR HERE, ANYWHERE.
>> WE HAVE YOUNG ONES TOO, WE
HAVE FIRST GRADERS, WE WANT THEM
TO KNOW THAT SOMETHING BAD
HAPPENED.
WE HAVE TO TELL THEM SOMETHING.
WE HAVEN'T SAID ANYTHING YET.
YES, SOMETHING BAD HAPPENED BUT
IT'S VERY USUAL AND THE BAD MAN
CAN'T HURT ANYONE ANYMORE.
THAT'S HOW WE WOULD, AS FIRST
GRADERS WE WOULD APPROACH THAT.
AND WE JUST NEED TO WORK TO MAKE
OUR COMMUNITY BETTER, AND NOT TO
BE AFRAID, YOU'RE SAFE WITH
MOMMY AND DADDY.
YOU'RE SAFE.
>> NO DOUBT YOU'VE HAD TO
COUNCIL PEOPLE WHO HAVE LOST
LOVED ONES, WHAT DO YOU SAY IN
THAT -- IS THERE ANYTHING TO
SAY OR IS IT JUST LISTEN?
>> THERE ARE THINGS TO SAY, BUT
I THINK OFTEN TIMES WE'RE
INCLINED TO WANT TO SAY THINGS
FIRST.
I THINK LISTENING IS THE FIRST
RESPONSE, IS TO LISTEN TO
PEOPLE'S GRIEF, LISTEN TO WHAT
THEY'RE -- EVEN IF THEY CAN'T
ARTICULATE NOT COMING IN
THINKING THAT A CERTAIN WORD,
PHRASE OR EVEN PEOPLE OF FAITH,
CERTAIN SCRIPTURES WILL JUST
SOLVE OR HEAL INSTANTLY.
BUT THOSE WORDS OF SCRIPTURE,
THOSE WORDS ARE SIGNIFICANT.
BUT REALIZING THAT WE HAVE TO
CONTINUE TO LISTEN AND TO FIND
APPROPRIATE WAYS WITH THEM TO
FIND EXPRESSION AND A MEANING
THAT COME OUT OF OUR TRADITIONS.
FOLKS I COUNCIL IN MY OWN
TRADITION.
THAT WOULD BE WHAT WE WOULD DRAW
UPON IN OUR CHRISTIAN FAITH.
>> THE LOSS OF A CHILD IS
SOMETHING -- THAT PAIN NEVER
GOES AWAY.
>> IT'S REALLY HORRIBLE.
AND WHEN YOU SEE THE PARENTS
WAILING LIKE THAT, YOU REALIZE,
THAT'S HOW WE WOULD BE IF WE
WERE THERE TOO.
THESE ARE ALL OF OUR CHILDREN.
AND SO -- I THINK MATT SAID IT
VERY WELL, YOU TAKE YOUR CUES,
SEE WHERE THE PERSON'S AT.
THERE'S ALL DIFFERENT KINDS OF
PEOPLE.
SOME PEOPLE WILL LIKE A
THEOLOGICAL EXPLANATION.
NOAH'S MOTHER, VERONICA, I TOLD
HER THIS MORNING, WHERE IS THE
6-YEAR-OLD INSIDE OF YOU, WHERE
DID IT GO?
SHE SAID, WELL, IT'S STILL IN
ME.
IN A SENSE, THERE'S A SPIRITUAL
IDEA THAT THERE REALLY IS NO
DEATH AND IT'S JUST
TRANSFORMATION AS WE, THROUGH
NATURE, GROW.
OUR 6-YEAR-OLD IS STILL
SURROUNDED BY THE GREATER ASPECT
OF OURSELVES AS WE GROW AND
MATURE.
AND SO IT'S A LEAP OF FAITH TO
SAY AFTER WE LEAVE OUR BODY THAT
WE BECOME PART OF A GREATER
MATRIX OR A GREATER MOTIF IN THE
UNIVERSE.
>> I APPRECIATE BOTH OF YOU FOR
BEING WITH US TONIGHT, BUT ALSO
JUST BEING ON THE STAGE AND WHAT
YOU SAID, I THOUGHT IT WAS
EXTRAORDINARILY POWERFUL.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> WISH YOU THE BEST.
THANK YOU.
>>> WHEN WE COME BACK,
REMEMBERING PRINCIPAL DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG.
WITH HER CHILDREN AND HER
HUSBAND.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[ Female Announcer ] BORN
FROM THE SWEET MONK FRUIT,
SOMETHING THIS DELICIOUS
COULD ONLY COME FROM NATURE.
NEW NECTRESSE.
THE 100% NATURAL
NO-CALORIE SWEETENER
MADE FROM THE GOODNESS
OF FRUIT.
NEW NECTRESSE.
SWEETNESS NATURALLY.
>>> THE PRINCIPAL WHO -- GOD
BLESS HER -- LOST HER LIFE.
SHE WAS A VERY SPECIAL PERSON.
AND ALL THE PARENTS KNEW THAT.
>> THE PRINCIPAL OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY WAS RESPECTED AND
ADMIRED BY THE TEACHERS AND
PARENTS AND LOVED BY THE
STUDENTS AS WELL.
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG WAS HER NAME,
WE MENTIONED HER BEFORE,
SHE BECAME PRINCIPAL TWO YEARS
AGO, SHE WAS A MOM OF ONE OF THE
FIRST GRADERS, SHE NEVER SAW HER
WITHOUT A SMILE, ON THAT AWFUL
DAY AT THAT SCHOOL WHO SURVIVED,
SAY DAWN DIED PROTECTING THEM,
CONFRONTING THE GUNMAN HERSELF.
IT WAS A TERRIBLE LOSS OF A
BELOVED PRINCIPAL, MORE
IMPORTANTLY, OF A WIFE, MOTHER
AND GRANDMOTHER.
TONIGHT DAWN HOCHSPRUNG'S
DAUGHTER, POSTED THIS
PICTURE ON TWITTER OF PRESIDENT
OBAMA HOLDING DAWN HOCHSPRUNG'S
GRANDDAUGHTER.
MY MOM WOULD BE SO PROUD TO SEE
PRESIDENT OBAMA HOLDING HER
GRANDDAUGHTER BUT NOT AS PROUD
AS I AM OF HER.
GARY TUCHMAN SPOKE WITH DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG'S HUSBAND AND KIDS
ABOUT THE REMARKABLE WOMAN SHE
WAS.
>> Reporter: PRINCIPAL DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG WAS QUITE A BIT
YOUNGER THAN HER HUSBAND GEORGE,
WHEN THEY GOT MARRIED TEN YEARS
AGO, GEORGE WAS MARRYING HIS
BOSS.
>> SHE WAS AN ASSISTANT
PRINCIPAL AT OUR SCHOOL, AND I
WAS A 7th GRADE MATH TEACHER AT
THAT TIME.
AND I JUST FELL IN LOVE WITH
HER.
>> GEORGE MADE THE BIG DECISION,
THE TIME HAD COME TO PROPOSE.
>> SHE TURNED ME DOWN FIVE
TIMES.
>> YOU ASKED HER TO MARRY YOU,
BUT SHE TURNED YOU DOWN?
>> FIVE TIMES.
>> WHAT ABOUT THE SIXTH TIME?
>> THE SIXTH TIME I WAITED UNTIL
IT WASN'T SUCH ROUGH SAILING.
>> Reporter: GEORGE HAD BEEN
POPPING THE QUESTION ON A
SAILBOAT THEY BOUGHT TOGETHER.
>> WE GOT MARRIED ON THE SWOOP
OUT OF MYSTIC.
BETH, AMY AND ANN ARE GEORGE'S
DAUGHTERS FROM HIS FIRST
MARRIAGE.
ERICA IS DAWN'S DAUGHTER FROM
HER FIRST MARRIAGE.
HER OTHER DAUGHTER TINA WAS OUT
WHILE WE WERE AT THE HOUSE.
THEY'RE A BLENDED BUT VERY CLOSE
FAMILY WITH 11 GRANDCHILDREN.
>> WE BUILT THIS BEAUTIFUL HOUSE
IN THE ADIRONDACKS, THE DREAM
WAS, CHRONOLOGICAL DREAM, IT WAS
GOING TO BE DAWN'S HOUSE,
BECAUSE I WAS GOING TO DIE.
I'M MUCH OLDER THAN DAWN.
IT WAS GOING TO BE DAWN'S HOUSE,
DAWN'S GRANDCHILDREN, ALL THESE
CHILDREN COULD USE THE HOUSE ON
THE LAKE AND IT WOULD BE
WONDERFUL.
WE BUILT ROOMS DOWNSTAIRS FOR
KIDS AND IT WAS GOING TO BE
DAWN'S HOUSE ULTIMATELY.
WITH ALL THE CHILDREN.
ALL THE CHILDREN.
AND NOW IT'S ME.
I CAN'T -- I DON'T THINK I CAN
DO THAT.
>> I WANT TO REITERATE TO YOU,
GEORGE, YOU HAVE THESE BEAUTIFUL
DAUGHTERS AND SON IN LAWS AND
GRANDCHILDREN AND EVERYONE WILL
BE HERE TO TAKE CARE OF YOU.
IS THAT RIGHT, LADIES?
>> OF COURSE.
>> MY JOB HAS ALWAYS BEEN TO
TAKE CARE OF OTHER PEOPLE.
>> IT'S ALL RIGHT IF SOME PEOPLE
TAKE CARE OF YOU FOR A WHILE?
>> NO ONE TAKES CARE OF ME.
>> STOP BEING SO STUBBORN.
>> Reporter: GEORGE STILL TAUGHT
AT THE MIDDLE SCHOOL WHERE THEY
MET.
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE DAY FRIDAY,
THIS IS HOW GEORGE FOUND OUT
WHAT HAPPENED.
>> ONE OF THE KIDS CAME UP WITH
A COMPUTER AND SAID, SOMETHING'S
HAPPENING AT SANDY HOOK SCHOOL
AND YOUR WIFE'S BEEN KILLED.
>> GEORGE RACED OUT OF SCHOOL
AND INTO A NIGHTMARE, LIKE ALL
THE FAMILIES OF VICTIMS THEY
WANT TO KNOW MORE.
AND ON THIS DAY THEY HAVE
LEARNED MORE.
TWO TEACHERS WHO SURVIVED SAID
THEY WERE HAVING A MEETING WITH
DAWN WHEN THE SHOTS STARTED
RINGING OUT.
>> SHE PUT HERSELF IN JEOPARDY,
AND I HAVE BEEN ANGRY ABOUT THAT
UNTIL JUST NOW, TODAY, WHEN I
MET THE TWO WOMEN SHE TOLD TO GO
UNDER SHELTER WHILE SHE ACTUALLY
CONFRONTED THE GUNMAN.
SHE COULD HAVE AVOIDED THAT.
AND SHE DIDN'T.
I KNEW SHE WOULDN'T.
I'M NOT ANGRY ANYMORE.
I'M NOT ANGRY.
I'M JUST VERY SAD.
THEY SAID, WE'RE AT THE MEETING,
THERE WERE GUNSHOTS, SOMEBODY
SHOT THE WINDOW, SOMEBODY CAME
IN, INTO THE -- NOT INTO THE
OFFICE BUT INTO THE BUILDING,
THE FOYER OF THE BUILDING AND
DAWN TOLD US TO GO HIDE AND SHE
AND AT LEAST ONE OTHER TEACHER
RAN OUT AND ACTUALLY TRIED TO
SUBDUE THE KILLER.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE THAT COMES
FROM, DAWN WAS ALL OF 5'2".
>> EVERYONE HERE IS PROUD, NO
ONE MORE SO THAN ERICA, WHO SAID
HER MOM WAS ALWAYS THERE FOR HER
DAUGHTERS.
>> EVERY GAME SHE WAS THERE,
EVERY PRACTICING WITH ALL OF MY
SISTER'S CHEERLEADING STUFF SHE
WAS THERE, EVERY DANCE
COMPETITION.
SHE WAS DOING HOME WORK ON THE
BLEACHERS.
SHE WAS THERE.
AND SHE WAS MY ROCK.
MY ROCK.
>> AND NOW SHE IS A HERO TOO.
>> FINAL THING I WANT TO ASK
YOU, WHAT WOULD YOU SAY TO YOUR
MOM RIGHT NOW?
>> COME BACK.
JUST COME BACK.
>> GARY TUCHMAN JOINS ME NOW
LIVE.
I GUESS SOME PEOPLE DON'T
UNDERSTAND WHY PEOPLE WOULD TALK
AT A TIME LIKE THIS.
WHAT I FOUND IS OFTEN TIMES
PEOPLE WANT YOU TO KNOW ABOUT
THEIR LOVED ONE.
WANT YOU TO KNOW ABOUT THE LIFE
THEY LIVED, NOT JUST HOW THEIR
LIFE ENDED.
>> THAT'S RIGHT, ANDERSON.
AND THEY ARE SUCH A WONDERFUL
AND AMAZING FAMILY.
WE'RE SO GRATEFUL THEY LET US
INTO THEIR HOME ON A DAY LIKE
THIS.
IT'S VERY IMPORTANT FOR THEM TO
STAY CLOSE AND STAY UNITED.
THAT'S WHAT WILL GIVE THEM
STRENGTH.
OF THE FIVE DAUGHTERS, TWO OF
THEM LIVE IN CONNECTICUT.
ONE LIVES IN PENNSYLVANIA, ONE
IN NEW HAMPSHIRE, ONE LIVES IN
LONDON, THEY PLAN TO STAY
TOGETHER FOR A LONG TIME TO GIVE
THEIR FATHER GEORGE STRENGTH.
THEY HAVE A HAPPY EVENT COMING
UP IN JULY.
ERICA, THE YOUNG LADY WE TALKED
TO, SHE'S THE ONLY ONE OF THE
FIVE DAUGHTERS THAT ISN'T
MARRIED.
SHE IS GETTING MARRIED IN JULY.
THEY ALL BELIEVE THAT THEIR
MOTHER'S SPIRIT WILL BE THERE
WITH THEM AT THE WEDDING
CEREMONY IN JULY.
ANDERSON?
>> APPRECIATE THE REPORTING,
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
JANET VULMER, A KINDERGARTEN
TEACHER AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
JOINS ME LIVE.
I SPOKE TO YOU ON THE PHONE
FRIDAY.
I'VE BEEN THINKING ABOUT YOU ALL
WEEKEND.
I THINK HEROES ARE TEACHERS
EVERY DAY AROUND THE COUNTRY.
I FIND -- I JUST THINK WHAT YOU
DID WAS SO HEROIC.
YOU -- EXPLAIN AGAIN, YOU
HEARD -- YOU KNEW SOMETHING WAS
GOING WRONG.
HOW?
>> WELL, I MEAN WE WERE IN OUR
CLASSROOM, WE HEARD WHAT SOUNDED
LIKE GUNSHOTS, NOISES.
>> YOU HEARD THAT --
>> WELL, THERE WAS A LOUD
SPEAKER, THE P.A. SYSTEM WAS NOT
WORKING IN THE WAY IT NORMALLY
IS, YOU DON'T USUALLY HEAR
THINGS UNLESS SOMEONE MAKES AN
ANNOUNCEMENT.
THERE WERE NOISES THAT DIDN'T
SOUND CORRECT.
THERE WAS NO ONE TELLING US IT
WAS A DRILL.
WE JUST THOUGHT SOMETHING WAS
NOT RIGHT.
WE TOOK THE CHILDREN AND WENT
INTO A LOCKDOWN, WE GO TO A
CERTAIN PLACE IN THE ROOM.
WE PULL THE BLINDS DOWN, WE LOCK
THE CLASSROOM DOORS AND WE COVER
THE WINDOW AT THE DOOR.
>> THIS IS SOMETHING YOU HAD
PRACTICED.
>> ABOUT A MONTH OR SO BEFORE,
DAWN MAKES SURE WE DO THAT.
AND WE GO TO A SAFE PLACE AND
TYPICALLY WHEN IT'S A DRILL THEY
TELL US, OKAY, AND WE EVEN
EXITED THE BUILDING FOLLOWING A
CERTAIN PATH.
IF THERE WAS AN EMERGENCY WE
WOULD GO DOWN TO THE SANDY HOOK
FIREHOUSE AND GATHER THERE,
WHICH IS WHAT WE DID THAT DAY.
WE KNEW THAT --
>> BUT YOU SAT THE KIDS DOWN.
>> WE SAT IN THE CUBBY AREA,
AWAY FROM THE DOOR SO NO ONE
COULD SEE US, READ THEM A STORY,
TALKED TO THEM.
THEY KEPT SAYING HOW COME WE'RE
HERE FOR SO LONG.
WELL, IT WILL BE A LITTLE
LONGER.
WHEN THEY'RE 5 YOU TELL THEM
WHATEVER YOU DO TO KEEP THEM
SAFE AND KEEP THEM CALM.
>> THIS IS WHAT I'VE BEEN
THINKING ABOUT ALL WEEKEND,
THOUGH, THE COURAGE FOR YOU TO
BE ABLE TO SIT THERE AND READ A
STORY AND KEEP THEM CALM --
>> I THINK THE ADRENALINE KICKS
IN AND YOU DO WHAT YOU HAVE TO
DO.
THERE WERE TWO OTHER PEOPLE IN
THE ROOM HELPING ME WITH PULLING
DOWN THE BLINDS AND THAT.
I WAS FOCUSED ON THE KIDS AND
JUST KEEPING THEM SAFE.
I'M NOT ABOUT TO TELL THEM THAT
I THINK SOMETHING IS VERY BAD OR
VERY WRONG.
SO WE WAITED AND WAITED AND IT
SEEMED LIKE A VERY LONG TIME.
MAYBE IT WAS 20 MINUTES, A HALF
HOUR, I'M NOT SURE.
THERE WERE KNOCKS AT THE DOOR.
IT WAS POLICE, SOMEONE, TELLING
US WE HAD TO LEAVE.
DIDN'T WANT TO OPEN THE DOOR AT
FIRST BUT WE DID.
YOU KNOW, THEY SAID HAVE THE
CHILDREN WALK, HOLD HANDS, COVER
THEIR EYES IF THEY COULD
BECAUSE, YOU KNOW, HE DIDN'T SAY
WHY.
HAVE THEM COVER THEIR EYES.
AT 5, COVERING THEIR EYES AND
WALKING ISN'T SO EASY.
I HAD THEM LOOK TOWARDS THE WALL
AND WE WENT DOWN THE HALL AND
OUT OF THE BUILDING.
I SAID BOYS AND GIRLS, REMEMBER
THE ADVENTURE WE HAD, WE ALL
WALKED TO THE FIREHOUSE?
WE'RE ALL GOING TO DO THAT
AGAIN.
BY THEN THE DRIVEWAY OF THE
SCHOOL WAS FILLED WITH A LOT OF
POLICE AND SIRENS AND THAT BUT
YOU KNOW --
>> HOW ARE YOU HOLING UP?
>> AGAIN, ADRENALINE, YOU'RE
MOVING, YOU'RE MOVE, YOU KNOW
YOU HAVE TO GET TO SAFETY.
I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT THE SITUATION
WAS REALLY OCCURRING.
WE DIDN'T HAVE ANY INFORMATION.
>> BUT HOW ARE YOU HOLDING UP
NOW?
>> HOW AM I HOLDING UP NOW.
>> YOU KNEW A LOT OF THESE KIDS.
>> TEN OF THE CHILDREN WERE IN
MY CLASS LAST YEAR.
TEN OF THE KIDS WHO ARE DEAD
NOW.
WHEN I HEARD THOSE NAMES, IT'S
TOUGH.
IT'S TOUGH.
YOU KNOW?
I'M WANTING TO ATTEND SOME OF
THE SERVICES, I'M SURE SOME
FAMILIES WANT PRIVACY.
THERE'S A FEW CHILDREN WHO I'VE
HAD NOT JUST THEM, I'VE HAD
THEIR SIBLINGS AND IN ONE CASE
I'VE HAD ALL THREE.
THEIR FAMILIES WE'RE CLOSE WITH.
AT SANDY HOOK SCHOOL WE'RE A
TIGHT-KNIT GROUP.
I LIVE IN THE COMMUNITY ALSO.
>> DAWN AND ALL THE OTHERS,
OBVIOUSLY YOU WORKED WITH THEM.
>> YES.
>> WHAT DO YOU WANT PEOPLE TO
KNOW ABOUT THEM, ABOUT THIS
COMMUNITY, ABOUT --
>> I WANT THEM TO BE ABLE TO
COME BACK TO SCHOOL.
I DON'T KNOW IF WE'LL COME BACK
TO SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
I'M HEARING WE'LL POSSIBLY BE
MOVED TO ANOTHER BUILDING
SOMEWHERE ELSE.
WE DO NEED TO GET THE KIDS BACK
IN SCHOOL.
WE NEED TO SEE THEM.
IT WAS HELPFUL TONIGHT TO SEE
SOME FAMILIES.
THEY WERE ALL CALLING US HEROES.
WE DON'T FEEL LIKE THAT.
WE DID WHAT WE NEEDED TO DO AND
KEPT THEIR CHILDREN SAFE AND,
YOU KNOW, I WAS ABLE TO TELL
EVERYBODY IN MY CLASS YOUR KIDS
ARE SAFE.
THAT MADE ME FEEL GOOD.
>> YOU'RE A HERO TO ME AND I
THINK TO A LOT OF PEOPLE.
>> THANK YOU.
>> I APPRECIATE YOU TALKING.
>> ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
>> AMAZING.
COMING UP, WE WANT TO PLAY YOU
MORE OF PRESIDENT OBAMA'S SPEECH
AT THE MEMORIAL SERVICE TONIGHT.
AT ONE POINT PRESIDENT ASKING IF
WE CAN HONESTLY SAY WE ARE DOING
ENOUGH TO KEEP OUR CHILDREN SAFE
FROM HARM.
>> CAN WE SAY WE'RE TRULY DOING
ENOUGH TO GIVE ALL THE CHILDREN
OF THIS COUNTRY THE CHANCE THEY
DESERVE TO LIVE OUT THEIR LIVES
AND HAPPINESS AND WITH PURPOSE?
I'VE BEEN REFLECTING ON THIS THE
LAST FEW DAYS.
IF WE'RE HONEST WITH OURSELVES,
THE ANSWER IS NO.
WE'RE NOT DOING ENOUGH.
>>> WE WANT TO SHARE A VIDEO
WITH YOU.
IT'S THE KIND OF VIDEO, FRANKLY,
ALL PARENTS TAKE OF THEIR
CHILDREN, A VIDEO CHRONICLING
THE SMALL MOMENTS, THE SWEET
MOMENTS, THE MOMENTS THAT MAKE
UP A CHILDHOOD.
IT'S A VIDEO OF ONE OF THE
CHILDREN WHO DIED IN THIS
TERRIBLE TRAGEDY, A BEAUTIFUL
LITTLE GIRL, 6 YEARS OLD, HER
NAME ANA MARQUEZ-GREENE.
HER BROTHER, ISAIAH WAS ALSO AT
THE SCHOOL.
HE WAS NOT HARMED.
ANA'S FATHER GAVE US PERMISSION
TO SHOW THIS VIDEO.
OTHERWISE WE WOULDN'T SHOW IT.
THEY WANT YOU TO SEE HER AS SHE
WAS, SINGING, MAKING MUSIC WITH
HER BROTHER AND PRAISING GOD.
TONIGHT WE REMEMBER ANA, WE
REMEMBER ALL THE CHILDREN.
>> COME NOW ALL MIGHTY KING.
>> ONE, TWO, THREE, READY AND
GO.
♪ COME NOW ALMIGHTY KING
♪ HELP US TO SEE
♪
♪ AMEN
>> AMEN.
IT'S BEEN AN INCREDIBLY
EMOTIONAL NIGHT HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AS IT HAS BEEN THE
LAST SEVERAL NIGHTS AS THE
COMMUNE CAME TOGETHER FOR THAT
MEMORIAL SERVICE AT THE HIGH
SCHOOL JUST BEHIND ME.
PRESIDENT OBAMA MET WITH
VICTIM'S FAMILIES AND SPOKE AT
THE SERVICE.
WE WANT TO PLAY YOU MORE OF WHAT
HE SAID TONIGHT WITH SINCERE
HOPE THAT THE PRESIDENT'S WORDS
BROUGHT SOME MEASURE OF COMFORT,
SOME SMALL MEASURE OF COMFORT IN
SOME WAY TO THE PEOPLE OF
NEWTOWN TONIGHT.
>> THIS IS OUR FIRST TASK,
CARING FOR OUR CHILDREN.
IT'S OUR FIRST JOB.
IF WE DON'T GET THAT RIGHT, WE
DON'T GET ANYTHING RIGHT.
THAT'S HOW, AS A SOCIETY, WE
WILL BE JUDGED.
AND BY THAT MEASURE, CAN WE
TRULY SAY AS A NATION THAT WE'RE
MEETING OUR OBLIGATIONS?
CAN WE HONESTLY SAY THAT WE'RE
DOING ENOUGH TO KEEP OUR
CHILDREN, ALL OF THEM, SAFE FROM
HARM?
>> I'VE BEEN REFLECTING ON THIS
THE LAST FEW DAYS, IF WE'RE
HONEST WITH OURSELVES, THE
ANSWER IS NO.
WE'RE NOT DOING ENOUGH.
AND WE WILL HAVE TO CHANGE.
SINCE I'VE BEEN PRESIDENT, THIS
IS THE FOURTH TIME WE HAVE COME
TOGETHER TO COMFORT A GRIEVING
COMMUNITY TORN APART BY MASS
SHOOTINGS.
FOURTH TIME WE'VE HUGGED
SURVIVORS.
FOURTH TIME WE'VE CONSOLED THE
FAMILIES OF VICTIMS.
AND IN BETWEEN THERE HAVE BEEN
AN ENDLESS SHOOTINGS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY, ALMOST DAILY REPORTS OF
VICTIM, MANY OF THEM CHILDREN,
IN SMALL TOWNS AND BIG CITIES
ALL ACROSS AMERICA.
VICTIMS WHOSE MUCH OF THE TIME
THEY'RE ONLY FAULT WAS BEING IN
THE WRONG PLACE AT THE WRONG
TIME.
WE CAN'T TOLERATE THIS ANYMORE.
THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
AND TO END THEM WE MUST CHANGE.
WE WILL BE TOLD THAT THE CAUSES
OF SUCH VIOLENCE ARE COMPLEX AND
THAT IS TRUE.
NO SINGLE LAW, NO SET OF LAWS
CAN ELIMINATE EVIL FROM THE
WORLD OR PREVENT EVERY SENSELESS
ACT OF VIOLENCE IN OUR SOCIETY.
BUT THAT CAN'T BE AN EXCUSE FOR
INACTION.
SURELY WE CAN DO BETTER THAN
THIS.
IF THERE'S EVEN ONE STEP WE CAN
TAKE TO SAVE ANOTHER CHILD OR
ANOTHER PARENT OR ANOTHER TOWN
FROM THE GRIEF THAT'S VISITED
TUCSON AND AURORA AND OAK CREEK
AND NEWTOWN AND COMMUNITIES
FROM COLUMBINE TO BLACKSBURG
BEFORE THAT, THEN SURELY WE HAVE
AN OBLIGATION TO TRY.
IN THE COMING WEEKS I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT TO MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS TO PARENTS
AND EDUCATORS IN AN EFFORT AIMED
AT PREVENTING MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS.
BECAUSE WHAT CHOICE DO WE HAVE.
WE CAN'T ACCEPT EVENTS LIKE THIS
AS ROUTINE.
ARE WE REALLY PREPARED TO SAY
THAT WE'RE POWERLESS IN THE FACE
OF SUCH CARNAGE?
THAT THE POLITICS ARE TOO HARD?
ARE WE PREPARED TO SAY THAT SUCH
VIOLENCE VISITED ON OUR CHILDREN
YEAR AFTER YEAR AFTER YEAR IS
SOMEHOW THE PRICE OF OUR
FREEDOM?
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA EARLIER
TONIGHT SPEAKING AT THE HIGH
SCHOOL JUST BEHIND US WOLF
BLITZER JOIN ME NOW LIVE.
I WAS WONDERING ABOUT YOUR
THOUGHTS WHILE LISTENING TO THE
PRESIDENT.
>> YOU KNOW, HE DID TONIGHT WHAT
HE DIDN'T DO THE EARLIER TIMES.
HE TRIED TO COMFORT THE NATION.
HE SPECIFICALLY PROMISED THAT HE
WOULD TAKE STEPS, HE DIDN'T GO
INTO DETAILS, TAKE STEPS TO TRY
TO MAKE SURE THAT THESE
SENSELESS KILLINGS DON'T HAPPEN
AGAIN, EVEN IF HE CAN SAVE A FEW
LIVES.
OBVIOUSLY WHAT HE'S REFERRING TO
IS LEGISLATION DEALING WITH GUN
CONTROL.
>> AND ALSO MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES.
>> I THINK THERE'S A LOT OF
THINGS POTENTIALLY HE CAN DO.
THERE WILL BE A POLITICAL FIGHT.
OBVIOUSLY THE HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES IN THE SENATE,
THERE ARE NO GUARANTEES.
HE DID MAKE THAT COMMITMENT, HE
PROMISED HE WAS GOING TO DO, AND
I THINK MAYOR BLOOMBERG OF NEW
YORK WANTS HIM TO DO, NOT JUST
TALK A LITTLE BIT, BUT START
TAKING SOME ACTION.
>> IT'S SOMETHING HE HAD TALKED
ABOUT BEFORE BECOMING PRESIDENT.
>> RIGHT.
>> BUT NOT SOMETHING HE ACTUALLY
PURSUED IN OFFICE.
>> HE DIDN'T JUST HAVE PROBLEMS
WITH REPUBLICANS WHO ARE OPPOSED
TO STRICTER GUN CONTROL.
THERE ARE PLENTY OF DEMOCRATS
OUT THERE WHO DON'T EVEN WANT TO
TALK ABOUT IT.
THEY THINK IT'S SUCH A LOSING
ISSUE FOR THEM POLITICALLY.
THEY DIDN'T WANT TO GET
INVOLVED.
INCLUDING THE SENATE MAJORITY
LEADER, HARRY REID.
HE HAS A LOT OF OTHER ISSUES, HE
HAS A FISCAL CLIFF.
THERE'S A WAR ZONE STILL GOING
ON IN AFGHANISTAN.
I THINK HE'S GOING TO DEAL WITH
THIS -- YOU KNOW, HE'S IN HIS
SECOND TERM, HE DOESN'T THE HAVE
TO WORRY ABOUT GETTING
RE-ELECTED.
I DON'T KNOW IF HE'LL SUCCEED.
I'VE BEEN IN WASHINGTON A LONG
TIME.
GUN CONTROL IS A TOUGH ISSUE BUT
I THINK IT'S SOMETHING HE'LL
CERTAINLY TRY.
>> A CRIME LIKE THIS HAS SHOCKED
THE NATION.
WHETHER IT LEADS TO CHANGE,
WE'LL HAVE TO SEE.
ON THE MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES.
YOU AND SANJAY WERE TALKING
ABOUT THIS EARLIER, MENTAL
HEALTH IS SOMETHING WHICH IS SO
ODDLY DEALT WITH THIS IN
COUNTRY --
>> RIGHT.
>> IT'S NOT DEALT WITH OR
CONSIDERED IN THE SAME WAY AS A
DISEASE LIKE CANR.