TO WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT MY
FAMILY AND MY WIFE AND MY
DAUGHTERS ARE TAKEN CARE OF AND
THAT IF THERE'S ANYTHING THAT I
CAN DO TO HELP ANYBODY AT ANY
TIME, ANYWHERE, I'D BE WILLING
TO DO THAT.
AS WE MOVE ON FROM WHAT HAPPENED
HERE, WHAT HAPPENED TO SO MANY
PEOPLE, LET IT NOT TURN INTO
SOMETHING THAT DEFINES US, BUT
SOMETHING THAT INSPIRES US TO BE
BETTER, TO BE MORE COMPASSIONATE
AND MORE HUMBLE PEOPLE.
>> A FATHER, A FAMILY, A
>> A NATION, WEARY OF THESE
TYPES OF TRAGEDIES, HOW DO WE
STOP THIS FROM COLLECTIVELY
HAPPENING AGAIN?
THOSE ARE THE QUESTIONS TO
PONDER.
I'M DON LEMON, LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
OUR COVERAGE CONTINUES.
>>> GOOD EVENING, EVERYONE, FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, I'M
ANDERSON COOPER, BACK FOR A
SPECIAL EDITION OF "360"
TONIGHT.
POLICE ARE STILL COMBING THROUGH
EVERY CRACK AND CREVICE, WHERE
THE GUNMAN SHOT AND KILLED SIX
AND SEVEN-YEAR-OLDS.
THEY'RE ALSO AT THE HOME OF THE
IDENTIFIED SHOOTER, TRYING TO
LEARN ANY CLUES, WHATEVER THEY
CAN, WHY HE DID WHAT HE DID, IN
PARTICULAR.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL BE HERE
TOMORROW VISITING THE FAMILIES
OF THE VICTIMS, THE 20 KIDS, AND
SIX ADULTS, ALSO TALKING TO
FIRST RESPONDERS.
AND TALKING AT A PRAYER VIGIL
TOMORROW EVENING.
AND WE ARE LEARNING MORE ABOUT
THESE YOUNG VICTIMS TONIGHT.
THE 12 LITTLE GIRLS, EIGHT BOYS
SHOT IN THE CLASSROOMS.
MOST OF WHAT WE ARE LEARNING IS
FROM THEIR PARENTS, PUBLICLY
SHARING THEIR GRIEF.
YOU WERE THERE EARLIER WHEN THE
FATHER OF EMILIE PARKER CAME OUT
OF HIS HOUSE AND WANTED TO TELL
PEOPLE.
WANTED TO TALK TO TV CAMERAS,
AND JUST TALK IN A VERY HUMAN
WAY ABOUT HIS DAUGHTER, ABOUT
WHAT SHE WAS LIKE.
ABOUT THE LIFE SHE LIVED.
>> Reporter: AND HE WAS VERY
CLEAR WHAT THE REASON HE WANTED
TO COME OUT AND FACE CAMERAS,
YOU KNOW, HE KNOWS THIS IS
NATIONAL TELEVISION.
HE WANTED TO MAKE SURE THAT
PEOPLE ACROSS THE COUNTRY KNEW
THAT HE WANTED TO SAY THANK YOU.
AND HE ALSO WANTED TO SHARE A
MESSAGE THAT WE'RE BETTER THAN
THIS.
THAT SOCIETY CANNOT BE DEFINED
BY THIS SINGLE ACT.
HE LOST A SIX-YEAR-OLD GIRL.
AND IT IS ONE THING TO THINK
ABOUT THE NUMBER.
IT IS A TOTALLY DIFFERENT THING
TO WATCH THIS MAN TALK, TO LOOK
AT THE PICTURES OF THIS
BEAUTIFUL GIRL.
AND TO FULLY COMPREHEND THAT
THIS FAMILY HAS SUFFERED A TRUE,
TRUE LOSS.
HERE IS WHAT HE TOLD US.
>> I WAS LEAVING TO WORK, AND --
SHE WOKE UP BEFORE I LEFT.
AND I ACTUALLY HAD BEEN TEACHING
HER PORTUGESE, SO OUR LAST
CONVERSATION WAS IN PORTUGESE.
SHE TOLD ME GOOD MORNING.
AND ASKED HOW I WAS DOING.
AND I SAID THAT I WAS DOING
WELL.
SHE SAID THAT SHE LOVED ME.
AND I GAVE HER A KISS AND I WAS
OUT THE DOOR.
AS THE DEEP PAIN BEGINS TO
SETTLE INTO OUR HEARTS WE FIND
COMFORT, REFLECTING ON THE
INCREDIBLE PERSON THAT EMILIE
WAS.
AND HOW MANY LIVES THAT SHE WAS
ABLE TO TOUCH IN HER SHORT TIME
HERE ON EARTH.
EM EMILIE WAS BRIGHT, CREATIVE,
VERY BRIGHT.
MY DAUGHTER, EMILIE, WOULD BE
THE FIRST ONE TO STAND AND GIVE
SUPPORT TO ALL OF THOSE VICTIMS,
BECAUSE THAT IS THE TYPE OF
PERSON SHE IS.
NOT BECAUSE OF ANY PARENTING
THAT MY WIFE AND I COULD HAVE
DONE, BUT BECAUSE THOSE WERE THE
GIFTS THAT WERE GIVEN TO HER BY
HER HEAVENLY FATHER.
>> AND HE ALSO SAID THAT HE WAS
VERY PROUD TO BE HER FATHER,
THAT HE WAS GOING TO BE THE BEST
FATHER HE COULD TO HIS TWO
REMAINING CHILDREN.
A THREE-YEAR-OLD AND A
FOUR-YEAR-OLD GIRL, HER SISTERS.
HE DID ALSO SAY THAT HE WANTED
TO MAKE SURE THAT HE EXTENDED
HIS CONDOLENCES TO THE SHOOTER'S
FAMILY, BECAUSE THEY ALSO
SUFFERED A LOSS, ANDERSON.
AND THE THING THAT IS REALLY
EXTRAORDINARY IS HOW HE IS ABLE
TO GET HIS MESSAGE OUT AND STILL
KEEP IT TOGETHER.
IT IS REALLY -- IT IS HARD TO --
TO WATCH.
AND TO COMPREHEND.
>> AND HOW DOES A FATHER TELL A
THREE AND A FOUR-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHTER THAT THEIR SISTER,
THEIR BIG SISTER IS GONE?
SO MANY -- WELL, IT IS JUST
INCREDIBLE.
APPRECIATE YOU REPORTING
TONIGHT.
RESIDENTS OF STRATFORD,
CONNECTICUT, REMEMBER ONE VICTIM
AS A FALLEN HERO.
PEOPLE WORE GREEN IN HONOR OF
VICTORIA SOTO WHO GREW UP IN
STRATFORD.
SHE WAS TWENTY-SEVEN YEARS OLD.
AND TAUGHT FIRST GRADE AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THEY ARE WEARING HER FAVORITE
COLOR, GREEN.
IT SOUNDS AS THOUGH THE
COMMUNITY REALLY ADORED THAT
TEACHER AND REALLY WANTED TO
SHOW THAT IN A VERY PUBLIC WAY.
>> YOU'RE EXACTLY RIGHT,
ANDERSON, THAT IS EXACTLY WHAT
HAPPENED HERE TONIGHT.
THE FAMILY SAYING THAT IT
BASICALLY ALL STARTED ON
FACEBOOK WITH A FACEBOOK
MESSAGE, LET'S GET TOGETHER.
LET'S FIND OUT A WAY TO HONOR
VICTORIA, VICKY, AS HER FAMILY
AND FRIENDS CALLED HER, VICTORIA
SOTO.
AND SO THAT IS WHAT THEY DID,
THEY CAME OUT TONIGHT IN FRONT
OF HER HIGH SCHOOL.
EVERYBODY WAS TALKING ABOUT HER,
SAYING SHE WANTED TO BE A
TEACHER EVER SINCE SHE WAS A
LITTLE GIRL.
AND THEY TALKED ABOUT HOW
DEDICATED THIS YOUNG WOMAN WAS
TO HER STUDENTS.
AND IN FACT, SHE DIDN'T EVEN
REFER TO THEM AS STUDENTS.
SHE ALWAYS REFERRED TO THEM AS
HER KIDS.
AND OUT HERE AS YOU CAN IMAGINE,
WITH HER SISTER BEING HERE, HER
BROTHER BEING HERE, HER PARENTS
BEING HERE, HER COUSIN, AS WELL,
GATHERED TOGETHER.
THEY STRUGGLED TO FIND WAYS TO
REMEMBER HER.
I SPOKE TO ONE YOUNG WOMAN WHO
KNEW VICKY SOTO THROUGHOUT HER
ENTIRE LIFE.
LISTEN TO HOW SHE SPOKE ABOUT
HER TONIGHT.
>> SHE WAS ALWAYS AT THE HOUSE,
SMILING.
SHE DROVE US TO CHEERLEADING
PRACTICES A COUPLE OF TIMES.
I'M ALSO A TEACHER, AND I CAN'T
EVEN IMAGINE GOING THROUGH WHAT
SHE WENT THROUGH.
I THINK PUTTING HERSELF OUT
THERE, SHE IS JUST AN ANGEL, AND
SHE JUST WENT STRAIGHT INTO
HEAVEN.
THERE IS NO DOUBT ABOUT THAT.
>> Reporter: AS YOU CAN SEE,
ANDERSON, OBVIOUSLY, IT IS AN
EMOTIONAL STRUGGLE FOR SO MANY
PEOPLE OUT HERE TONIGHT.
AT ONE MOMENT, CARLY SOTO, SHE
IS NINETEEN YEARS OLD, SHE STOOD
UP IN FRONT OF SEVERAL HUNDRED
PEOPLE GATHERED OUT HERE
TONIGHT.
AND SHE SPOKE JUST BRIEFLY, SHE
REMINDED THE AUDIENCE TO HUG
YOUR LOVED ONES, SHE SAID,
BECAUSE YOU JUST NEVER KNOW WHEN
YOU'RE GOING TO SEE THEM AGAIN.
IT WAS A VERY POWERFUL MOMENT AS
THE FAMILY PAID TRIBUTE TO A
WOMAN WHO THEY SAY WAS A
DEDICATED TEACHER.
A LOVING DAUGHTER, AND SOMEONE
WHO LOVED HER CHILDREN OR HER
STUDENTS.
ANDERSON?
>> OH, ONE FAMILY SAYS THEY OWE
THEIR SON'S LIFE TO VICKY SOTO.
THEY SPOKE TO KATE BALDWIN,
ABOUT THEIR SON YESTERDAY AND
HOW HE IS COPING WITH WHAT THEY
HAVE SEEN.
>> Reporter: ANDERSON, THEY HAD
TWO CHILDREN AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL YESTERDAY.
A SECOND GRADER AND THEIR SON IN
FIRST GRADE, WHO THEY SAY IT IS
A MIRACLE HE MADE IT OUT ALIVE
AFTER COMING FACE TO FACE WITH
THE SHOOTER.
>> AND THAT IS WHEN THEY HEARD
NOISES THAT HE DESCRIBED AS --
INITIALLY THEY THOUGHT WERE
HAMMERS FALLING.
AND THEN THEY REALIZED THAT IT
WAS GUNSHOTS.
AND MS. SOTO, WHO WAS AIDEN'S
TEACHER, HAD THE PRESENCE OF
MIND TO MOVE ALL OF THE CHILDREN
TO A DISTANCE AWAY FROM THE DOOR
ON THE SIDE OF THE ROOM, FURTARR
AWAY FROM THE DOOR.
AND THAT IS WHEN THE GUNMAN
BURST IN, DID NOT SAY A WORD, NO
FACIAL EXPRESSIONS, AND
PROCEEDED TO SHOOT THEIR
TEACHER.
AND THEY BASICALLY RAN RIGHT
NEXT TO THE GUY AND OUT THE
DOOR.
>> THEY RAN PAST THE GUY?
>> THEY RAN PAST THE GUY.
HE IS STILL STANDING IN THE
DOOR.
AND THEY RAN PAST HIM AND DOWN
THE HALLWAY, NEAR ONE OF THE
CLOSEST ROOMS TO THE MAIN
ENTRANCE.
AND AIDEN HAD THE PRESENCE OF
MIND TO HOLD THE DOOR FOR ONE OF
HIS CLASSMATES.
AND THERE WAS ANOTHER ONE OF HIS
CLASSMATES, A LITTLE BEHIND AND
WAITED FOR HIM.
AND THEN THEY ALL RAN TO THE
MAIN ROAD, ALL THE WAY DOWN.
>> Reporter: AND OF COURSE WE
ALL KNOW HIS TEACHER DIED IN
THAT CLASSROOM TRYING TO PROTECT
HER STUDENTS.
>> HE KNOWS HIS TEACHER WAS
SHOT.
DO YOU THINK HE KNOWS WHAT --
THAT SHE LIKELY DID NOT MAKE IT?
>> HE KEEPS ASKING ABOUT HER,
AND I THINK SHE IS REASSURING
HIMSELF THAT SHE IS GOING TO BE
OKAY.
HE REALLY -- REALLY CARED FOR
HIS TEACHER.
HE WAS VERY CLOSE WITH HER, AND
SHE REALLY LOVED HER CLASS.
AND HE KEEPS SAYING I REALLY
HOPE SHE IS OKAY.
I HOPE IT IS NOT HER.
HE KNOWS THAT SHE HAS BEEN HURT.
BUT HE DOESN'T KNOW THE END
RESULT.
HE KNOWS THE KIDS THAT HE SAW
GETTING SHOT.
HE DOESN'T KNOW THE OUTCOME.
SO I THINK HE IS REASSURING
HIMSELF IN HIS SIX-YEAR-OLD
MIND.
I KNOW HE IS PROCESSING IT.
BUT I THINK HE IS REASSURING
HIMSELF.
I THINK HE IS TELLING HIMSELF
THAT IT IS GOING TO BE OKAY.
WE HAD TO PUT THE SIGN OUT IN
THE FRONT TODAY ASKING PEOPLE
NOT THE RING THE DOOR BELL,
BECAUSE HE STILL HAS NOT
INTERNALIZED THE FACT THAT THIS
GUNMAN, THIS BAD GUY IS GONE.
AND HE WANTS TO KNOW IF THERE
ARE MORE BAD GUYS IN THE WORLD.
AND I DON'T KNOW HOW TO ANSWER
THAT QUESTION PROPERLY.
AND SO WHEN SOMEONE RINGS THE
DOOR BELL HE THINKS IT IS HIM
COMING BACK -- COMING FOR HIM.
AND SO HE -- YOU KNOW, HE -- SO
I THINK OUR BIGGEST CONCERN NOW
IS MAKING SURE THAT WE HANDLE
HIS SENSITIVE NATURE PROPERLY
AND CAREFULLY AND SUPPORT HIM.
AND SUPPORT OUR DAUGHTER,
BECAUSE SHE AGAIN DOES PROCESS
THINGS VERY DIFFERENTLY THAN HE
DOES.
SO THAT IS OUR JOB AS PARENTS
NOW, TO STAY CLOSE TO THEM.
HOLD THEM, HUG THEM, LOVE THEM,
AND LET THEM KNOW THAT THEY ARE
SAFE.
>> Reporter: THEY DID NOT WANT
THEIR CHILDREN TO BE PART OF THE
INTERVIEW, BUT I DID SPEND TIME
WITH THEM THIS MORNING.
AND AIDEN AND HIS SISTER, THEY
SEEMED IN HIGH SPIRITS, BUT
CLEARLY SHAKEN.
AND AS HARD AS IT HAS BEEN FOR
THIS FAMILY THEY SAY THAT THEIR
HEARTS GO OUT TO SO MANY OTHER
FAMILIES WHO CANNOT GO HOME AND
HUG THEIR CHILDREN TONIGHT.
ANDERSON?
>> YEAH, KATE, THANK YOU, ONE OF
THE BUSIEST PLACES IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, MAY HAVE BEEN THE
GRIEF COUNSELING CENTER.
BOTH VICTIMS AND THOSE AFFECTED
BY WHAT HAPPENED FRIDAY GOT THE
CHANCE TO SPEAK TO SOMEONE IF
THEY WANTED ABOUT WHAT THEY WERE
FEELING.
THE HEALING COMES IN HONORING
THOSE VICTIMS, THE GIANT
MEMORIAL TO THOSE KIDS.
JOINING US IS DR. SANJAY GUPTA
WHO WAS THERE EARLIER.
AND WE'RE LOOKING AT THE PICTURE
OF THE MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS THAT
SPRUNG UP.
AS SO OFTEN SPRINGS UP DURING
TRAGEDIES.
PEOPLE JUST SPONTANEOUSLY
EXPRESSING THEIR SORROW AND
GRIEF, IN WAYS LARGE AND SMALL.
YOU HAVE ACTUALLY BEEN LOOKING
AT STUDIES ABOUT HOW KIDS IN
THIS AGE RANGE, YOUNG KIDS, DEAL
WITH WITNESSING A TRAUMATIC
EVENT.
>> FIRST OF ALL, PTSD IS
SOMETHING WE THINK ABOUT WITH
ADULTS.
WE DON'T TALK ABOUT IT WITH
YOUNG KIDS, CHILDREN, IT EXISTS.
THEIR BEHAVIOR IS DIFFERENT.
THEY DON'T HAVE THE FLASHBACKS,
AND THE HYPER VIGILANCE THAT WE
ASSOCIATE WITH PTSD.
SOMETIMES YOU SEE IT IN THE WAY
THEY PLAY, OR DRESS.
THEY MAY ACT YOUNGER, THEY MAY
JUST HAVE BEHAVIOR THAT SEEMS
OUT OF SORTS.
AND OFTEN CARE GIVERS DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO MAKE OF IT.
AND IT CAN BE A FORM OF PTSD.
>> AND THE TIME TABLE, DOES IT
PLAY OUT IMMEDIATELY OR IS IT
SOMETHING THAT SHOWS UP MONTHS
LATER?
>> NO, IT OFTEN SHOWS UP VERY
EARLY.
AND THAT WAS A VERY IMPORTANT
POINT.
BECAUSE IF YOU NOTICE IT EARLY
THAT IS PRETTY NORMAL FOR BOTH
ADULTS AND CHILDREN ALIKE.
IF IT TURNS INTO ANXIETY AND
NIGHTMARES OR LOSS OF SLEEP,
THEN THAT IS TIME TO MAYBE GET
SOME HELP.
AND WE TALKED ABOUT IT LAST
NIGHT, ANDERSON, AND IF YOU LOOK
AT THE STUDIES, IT IS REALLY
COMPELLING STUFF IF SOMEBODY
GETS GOOD SLEEP.
GOOD QUALITY SLEEP.
YOU CAN PREDICT MUCH MORE
ACCURATELY HOW WELL THEY'RE
GOING TO BE ABLE TO COPE IN THE
LONG RUN.
AND THAT IS SLEEP -- LAST NIGHT,
TONIGHT, PARENTS WATCHING THEIR
CHILD'S SLEEP PATTERNS TONIGHT
IS REALLY IMPORTANT IN
PREDICTING THAT.
>> SOMETHING WE TALKED ABOUT A
COUPLE OF HOURS AGO, I JUST
THINK IT BEARS REPEATING.
I THINK IT HAS CONCERNED A LOT
OF PARENTS, PARENTS WHOSE KIDS
ARE ON THE SPECTRUM OF AUTISM,
OR HAS ASPERGERS.
YESTERDAY THERE WAS A QUOTE FROM
THE BROTHER WHO SAID HE BELIEVED
HIS BROTHER HAD A FORM OF
AUTISM, AND THAT HE ALSO HAD A
PERSONALITY DISORDER.
IT IS EASY TO LINK THOSE TWO
THINGS TOGETHER.
AUTISM IS NOT A PERSONALITY
DISORDER.
SO LET'S JUST CLARIFY AGAIN.
>> YES, BECAUSE AS YOU ALWAYS
SAY, ANDERSON, TERMS DO MATTER
HERE.
AND WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT AUTISM
OR ON THE AUTISM SPECTRUM, IS
WHAT THEY CALL IT.
IT IS A NEURO-DEVELOPMENTAL
DISORDER.
THAT IS SOMETHING THAT HAPPENS
FROM BIRTH, OR MAYBE A MENTAL
ILLNESS THAT COULD COME ON LATER
IN LIFE.
BUT THE CRUCIAL POINT HERE, IT
IS NOT ASSOCIATED WITH PLANNED
VIOLENCE.
IT JUST ISN'T.
>> I HAVE NEVER HEARD OF A YOUNG
PERSON WITH AUTISM COMMITTING A
PRE-PLANNED ACT OF VIOLENCE.
>> I HADN'T EITHER, BUT TODAY,
BECAUSE WE TALKED ABOUT IT LAST
NIGHT I WENT AND LOOKED AT THE
STUDIES AGAIN.
THE STUDY QUOTED WAS OF ABOUT
132 PEOPLE.
THAT WAS NOT A BIG STUDY, BUT
ONE OF THE ONLY ONES OUT THERE.
AND OUT OF THOSE, ONLY THREE,
MENTIONS OF VIOLENCE AND NONE OF
THEM PRE-PLANNED.
SO I THINK I CAN SAFELY SAY
THERE IS NO LINK BETWEEN AUTISM
SPECTRUM AND PRE-PLANNED
VIOLENCE, SO WE CAN DISPEL THAT.
>> AND I HAVE HEARD FROM A LOT
OF PARENTS ON TWITTER AND
ELSEWHERE, OUTRAGED THAT PEOPLE
ARE USING THE TERM "AUTISM" AND
LINKING IT TO THE SHOOTING.
>> YEAH, I HOPE THEY'RE
WATCHING.
BECAUSE I THINK IT IS AN
EDUCATIONAL POINT.
THAT IS JUST NOT TRUE, IT IS
JUST NOT TRUE.
>> WHAT SHOULD PARENTS BE
WATCHING FOR, DO YOU THINK IN
THE NEXT COUPLE OF DAYS?
>> I THINK YOU KNOW, THERE IS A
LOT OF NORMAL SORT OF GRIEF THAT
IS GOING ON.
I THINK OBVIOUSLY WITH CHILDREN
IT IS NOT GOING TO BE SORT OF
THE THING -- IT IS NOT GOING TO
BE THE THINGS THAT YOU MIGHT
EXPECT.
ADULTS OBVIOUSLY HAVE A MUCH
BETTER WAY OF VERBALIZING THESE
THINGS.
I THINK IT IS IMPORTANT FOR
PARENTS TO NOTE.
THIS IS NORMAL IN THE FIRST FEW
DAYS.
WHAT HAPPENS IS THAT IF IT
PROGRESSES LONGER TERM, THEN
PEOPLE DO NEED TO GET HELP.
THERE IS A HELP CENTER AVAILABLE
HERE, THERE IS NOT ENOUGH SORT
OF THINKING OF MENTAL ILLNESS OR
THESE TYPES OF PROBLEMS WITH
PHYSICAL ILLNESS AS IT IS.
WE TEND TO PUT THESE THINGS IN
DIFFERENT BUCKETS.
SO THE IDEA THAT YOU COULD THINK
OF MENTAL ILLNESS THE SAME WAY
WE THINK OF CARDIAC ISSUES,
DIABETES, CANCER.
IT IS STIGMATIZED, THERE ARE NOT
ENOUGH RESOURCES, BUT HOPEFULLY
IT WILL CATCH ON.
>> AND FOR PARENTS WHO HAVE A
CHILD WITH MENTAL ILLNESS
ISSUES, WE HAVE SEEN IN THE PAST
CASES, WITH THE VIRGINIA TECH
ISSUE, THE PARENTS TRIED TO GET
HELP FOR THE CHILD OR FOR THE
YOUNG ADULT.
AND UNLESS THAT PERSON CAN BE
PROVED TO BE VIOLENT OR IS A
THREAT TO THEMSELVES OR SOMEBODY
ELSE THEY OFTEN CAN'T GET HELP.
>> THAT IS RIGHT.
PARENTS CAN ANGUISH OVER THIS.
IT IS NOT THAT THEY MISSED THE
SIGNS, OFTEN THEY KNOW THE SIGNS
BUT COULDN'T GET HELP.
AND AT VIRGINIA TECH, THREE
QUARTERS OF THE STUDENTS HAD
PTSD, SO THIS CAN LAST A LONG
TIME.
>> IMPORTANT INFORMATION,
SANJAY, UP NEXT, OUR COVERAGES
CONTINUES FROM HERE IN NEWTOWN.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
MY WIFE TAKECENTRUM SILVER.
I' BEEN ON THE FENCE ABO IT.
THEN I READ AN ARTIE
ABOUT STUDY THAT OKED
AT THE LONG TERM HEALTH BENEFITS
OF TAKING MULTIVITAMINS.
HEY USED CENTR SILVER
F T STUDY...
SO I GUESS MY WIFE WAS RIGHT.
Male Anner ] CENTRUM.
WAYS YOUR MOSTOMPLET
HOW THEY'LL LIVE TOMORROW.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
>>> IF YOU'VE BEEN WATCHING A
LOT OF COVERAGE OF THIS TRAGEDY,
YOU NO DOUBT KNOW THE NAME OF
THE SHOOTER BY NOW.
WE ARE NOT DURING THIS BROADCAST
USING THE NAME OF THE SHOOTER.
YOU PROBABLY ALREADY KNOW,
THERE'S NO NEED TO REPEAT IT
OVER AND OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
OFTEN IT SEEMS THAT IN HISTORY
REMEMBERS THE NAMES OF MURDERERS
AND NOT THE NAMES OF VICTIMS.
AND I THINK THAT'S -- I JUST
THINK THAT IT SHOULDN'T BE.
SO WE'RE TRYING TO DO WHAT WE
CAN TO NOT CONTRIBUTE TO THAT
NAME BEING OUT THERE AND BEING
KNOWN AS A HOUSEHOLD NAME FROM
HERE ON OUT.
WITNESSES TO THE SHOOTING
YESTERDAY SAY THAT THE FIRST
SHOTS RANG OUT AND JUST AS THE
MORNING ANNOUNCEMENTS WERE BEING
READ AT THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
AND POLICE ARE TRYING TO HAMMER
DOWN EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED
BEFORE THAT MOMENT.
TOM FOREMAN BREAKS IT DOWN FOR
US RIGHT NOW WITH WHAT
INVESTIGATORS KNOW SO FAR.
>> POLICE ARE ESSENTIALLY
CONSTRUCTING A MAP OF ALL OF THE
PLACES THAT MIGHT HAVE HAD
CONNECTIONS TO THIS SHOOTER.
FOR EXAMPLE, HIS BROTHER'S
APARTMENT DOWN HERE IN NEW
JERSEY ACROSS NEW YORK UP INTO
CONNECTICUT.
HIS MOTHER'S HOUSE WHERE SHE WAS
FOUND DEAD.
ONLY ABOUT THREE MILES AWAY, OF
COURSE, THE SCHOOL.
TO TRY TO FIGURE OUT WHAT LED
HIM TO THIS SPOT AT THAT TIME
BECAUSE THEY DO BELIEVE THAT
SHORTLY AFTER MURDERING HIS
MOTHER, HE DID DRIVE THE FEW
MILES FROM HER HOUSE TO THIS
SCHOOL AND EMERGE IN THIS
PARKING LOT WITH WEAPONS VERY
MUCH LIKE THESE TO GO INTO THE
SCHOOL.
NOW, LET'S LOOK AT THE TIME LINE
OF WHAT HAPPENED.
THAT'S WHAT THEY'RE TRYING TO
RECONSTRUCT.
ABOUT 9:30 IN THE MORNING,
THAT'S WHEN WE BELIEVE BASED ON
EYEWITNESS ACCOUNTS AND POLICE
RADIO, THAT HE PROBABLY LEFT HIS
CAR, WE THINK THIS IS THE ONE
OVER HERE, BASED ON THE
INVESTIGATION, AND CAME UP TO
THE FRONT OF THE SCHOOL.
IT'S ALSO WHEN HE ENCOUNTERED
HIS FIRST OBSTACLE.
BECAUSE THESE SECURITY DOORS
WERE INSTALLED TO KEEP PEOPLE
OUT.
POLICE LATER SAID THE GLASS HAD
BEEN BROKEN OUT OF THESE.
THAT'S APPARENTLY HOW HE GOT
INTO THE SCHOOL WITH THOSE
WEAPONS.
WHAT WE KNOW FOR SURE IS BASED
ON POLICE REPORTS, BY 9:36, WE
HAD OUR FIRST CALLS INTO THE
POLICE STATION SAYING THAT
SHOOTING WAS OCCURRING INSIDE
THE SCHOOL AND, OF COURSE,
EVERYBODY WITHIN THE SCHOOL WAS
ALERTED TO THE SOUND OF THE
GUNFIRE.
IF THEY DIDN'T HEAR IT DIRECTLY,
THEY HEARD IT OVER THE P.A.
SYSTEM IN THIS SCHOOL WHERE
ANNOUNCEMENTS WERE BEING MADE AT
THAT TIME.
EVEN THOUGH ALL OF THE SHOOTING
TOOK PLACE IN A RELATIVELY SMALL
AREA UP HERE.
THIS IS ALSO SIGNIFICANT, BY
9:38, 2 TO 2 1/2 MINUTES LATER,
POLICE WERE SAYING IF NOT ALL
THE SHOOTING, A BULK OF THE
SHOOTING WAS OVER, A VERY SHORT
PERIOD OF TIME IN A VERY SMALL
AREA WHERE IT ALL SEEMED TO
OCCUR.
WHAT HAPPENED AFTER THAT?
WELL, IT PROGRESSED EVEN
FURTHER.
BY ABOUT 9:40 IN THE MORNING,
POLICE WERE CALLING FOR
EMERGENCY MEDICAL TECHNICIANS TO
COME THERE, FOR AMBULANCES TO
COME.
A FEW MINUTES LATER, THEY CALLED
FOR A WHOLE LOT MORE AMBULANCES
TO COME.
AND BY 9:50 OR SO IN THE
MORNING, THEY WERE ESSENTIALLY
SAYING THE SCENE WAS SECURE.
THEY HAD A SUSPECT WHO WAS DOWN.
THEY HAD CLEARED THE BUILDING.
THAT MANY OF THE CHILDREN WERE
BEING LED OUT, AS YOU CAN SEE IN
THIS PHOTOGRAPH FROM "THE
NEWTOWN BEE."
AND THAT THE SITUATION WAS MORE
OR LESS SECURE.
THERE IS STILL A LOT OF WORK TO
BE DONE OBVIOUSLY.
BUT AS YOU CAN SEE, AS WE LOOK
AT THIS TIME LINE CLOSER AND
CLOSER, IT'S COMING DOWN TO A
VERY SHORT PERIOD OF TIME, 20
MINUTES OR LESS FROM THE
BEGINNING TO THE END OF THIS IN
TERMS OF PEOPLE REALLY KNOWING
WHAT WAS HAPPENING.
AND NOW THIS HUGE, LONG, LONG
SEARCH TO UNDERSTAND WHY IT
HAPPENED.
ANDERSON?
>> TOM, THANKS VERY MUCH.
WE WANT TO GO TO OUR DAVID
ARIOSTO WHO'S IN THE
NEIGHBORHOOD WHERE THE MOTHER OF
THIS SHOOTER LIVED.
DAVID, WHAT ARE YOU LEARNING
ABOUT THIS LADY?
>> ANDERSON, THIS IS WHERE THAT
FIRST MURDER TOOK PLACE BEFORE
THE SHOOTER HEADED OVER TO THAT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE'VE TALKED TO NEIGHBORS IN AND
AROUND THE AREA HERE.
THEY PAINT A PICTURE OF A WOMAN
WHO WAS KILLED RIGHT BEFORE THAT
SHOOTING -- THEY DESCRIBE HER
SORT OF AS THIS PLEASURABLE
WOMAN, A WOMAN WHO WAS A VERY
PLEASANT PERSON TO BE AROUND.
SOMEONE WHO LOVED GARDENING,
LOVED LANDSCAPING, SOMEONE WHO
ATTENDED A MONTHLY DICE GAME
WITH MANY PEOPLE IN THE
NEIGHBORHOOD.
IT'S A TIGHT-KNIT COMMUNITY IN
THIS SOUTHWESTERN CONNECTICUT
TOWN.
AND EVEN THOUGH YOU CAN'T REALLY
GET A SENSE OF IT NOW, IT IS ONE
OF THE MORE PICTURESQUE PLACES
I'M STANDING IN.
ROLLING GREEN HILLS AND QUITE AN
AFFLUENT NEIGHBORHOOD, TWO AND
THREE-STORY HOMES.
THE THINKING IS PEOPLE MOVED TO
THIS AREA BECAUSE OF THE SCHOOL
SYSTEMS.
SO IT STRIKES A PARTICULAR CHORD
THAT THIS OCCURRED WITHIN AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
BUT THEN YOU ALSO HAVE THAT
OTHER SIDE, THE TALK OF THIS
WOMAN, NANCY LANZA, WHO
COLLECTED GUNS, SOME
HIGH-POWERED WEAPONS AS IN THAT
BUSHMASTER THAT WAS USED IN THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SHOOTING.
IT'S NOT CLEAR WHETHER SHE
ATTENDED SOME OF THE SHOOTING
RANGES IN THE AREA ALTHOUGH WE
KNOW THERE ARE AT LEAST THREE
SHOOTING RANGES WITHIN A 20-MILE
RANGE OF THIS AREA.
ONE OF THE WORKERS THAT I SPOKE
TO AT A LOCAL BUSINESS HERE SAID
THAT SHE OFTEN SHOWED HER
RIFLE -- SHOWED A RIFLE THAT SHE
HAD RECENTLY PURCHASE AND EVEN
BROUGHT HER CHILDREN TARGET
SHOOTING.
NOT CLEAR IF THAT OCCURRED AT
THOSE RANGES OR JUST IN AND
AROUND THE AREA.
ATF AND FEDERAL OFFICIALS WE'VE
SPOKEN TO, FBI, SAID THAT THAT
DIDN'T OCCUR.
THERE'S REALLY QUITE A BIT OF
CONFLICTING INFORMATION AS TO
WHAT TRANSPIRED HERE.
BUT ONE NEIGHBOR PERHAPS SORT OF
SAID IT BEST.
SOMETHING JUST DOESN'T QUITE ADD
UP AS TO WHO THIS WOMAN WAS, WHY
SHE WAS KILLED AND WHAT
TRANSPIRED IN REALLY THE MINUTES
AFTER HER DEATH.
>> YEAH, THERE ARE SO MANY
QUESTIONS STILL UNANSWERED, AT
THIS POINT
DAVID, APPRECIATE THE REPORTING.
WE'LL TAKE A SHORT BREAK.
OUR COVERAGE CONTINUES IN A
MOMENT.
CAN YOUR MOISTURIZER DO THAT?
[ Female Announcer ]
DERMATOLOGIST RECOMMENDED
Aveeno HAS AN OAT FORMULA,
NOW PROVEN
TO BUILD A MOISTURE RESERVE,
SO SKIN CAN REPLENISH ITSELF.
THAT'S HEALTHY SKIN FOR LIFE.
ONLY FROM Aveeno.
SHE ALSO LIKES
TO RIDE HER BIKE.
SHE KNOWS THE POTENTIAL
FOR MAKING OR LOSING MONEY
CAN POP UP ANYTIME.
THAT'S WHY SHE TRADES WITH
THE LEADER IN MOBILE TRADING.
SO SHE'S ALWAYS READY
TO TAKE ACTION,
NO MATTER HOW WILY...
OR WEIRD...
OR WONDERFULLY
THE MARKET'S BEHAVING...
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
Capella University understands
back from rough economic times.
Employees are being forced to do
more with less.
And the need for capable leaders
is greater than ever.
When you see these problems do
you take a step back,
or do you want to dive right in?
With a degree in business from
Capella University, you'll have
the knowledge to go further in
your career than you ever
thought possible.
Let's get started at CAPELLA.EDU
PICTURES>>> IN THIS HOUR AND INS
AHEAD, WE'RE TRYING TO FOCUS AS
MUCH AS WE CAN ON THE VICTIMS
AND LETTING YOU KNOW ABOUT THE
LIVES THEY LIVED, NOT JUST HOW
THEY LOST THEIR LIVES BUT THE
KIND OF LIVES THEY LIVED, WHO
THEY WERE.
AND TODAY WE'RE ABLE TO TELL YOU
MORE ABOUT THEM THAN WE WERE
YESTERDAY.
AND NO DOUBT TOMORROW WE'LL BE
ABLE TO TELL YOU EVEN MORE AS
FAMILY MEMBERS COME FORWARD AND
WANT TO SHARE THEIR GRIEF AND
WANT TO SHARE THEIR MEMORIES OF
THEIR LOVED ONES.
THOSE OF US FROM OUTSIDE ARE NOW
LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE WOMEN
AND THE CHILDREN WHO LOST THEIR
LIVES ON FRIDAY AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
TAKE A LOOK.
>> VICTORIA SOTO'S FAMILY SAYS
SHE HAD HER STUDENTS HUDDLED
BEHIND HER TRYING TO PROTECT
THEM WHEN SHE WAS SHOT AND
KILLED AT THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
HER COUSIN SAYS THE HARDEST PART
WAS WAITING TO HEAR WHETHER SHE
HAD SURVIVED OR NOT.
>> AT THAT POINT, IT WAS THE
HARDEST FOR THE WHOLE FAMILY,
JUST THE WAITING GAME.
TO RECEIVE WORD ON WHAT HAPPENED
TO VICKI'S CLASS.
>> ALSO KILLED, LAUREN RUSSO,
HIRED JUST LAST MONTH AS A
PERMANENT SUBSTITUTE TEACHER.
HER FAMILY SAYS SHE ALWAYS
WANTED TO BE A TEACHER SINCE
BEFORE SHE EVEN WENT TO
KINDERGARTEN.
THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST SAYS ON
HER WEB PAGE SHE HAS TWO
DAUGHTERS IN THEIR 20s, MARRIED
31 YEARS.
AND GOES TO A LAKE HOUSE WITH
HER HUSBAND, IN UPSTATE NEW YORK
AND THE PRINCIPAL, DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG SAYING SHE WAS
EXCITED ABOUT TEACHING.
>> TO LOSE SOMEBODY LIKE THAT IN
OUR DISTRICT, IT'S SAD.
>> SHE WAS A PERSONAL FRIEND AND
A WONDERFUL LEADER.
>> SHE HAD RECENTLY OVERSEEN THE
INSTALLATION OF A NEW SECURITY
SYSTEM REQUIRING EVERY VISITOR
AFTER 9:30 A.M. TO GET BUZZED IN
AND SHOW ID.
>> SHE TRULY DID BELIEVE IN
CREATING AN ENVIRONMENT WHERE
CHILDREN FELT SAFE.
I THINK THAT THAT'S REALLY THE
TRAGIC IRONY OF THIS ENTIRE
SITUATION.
>> SHE WAS ALSO A PARENT
HERSELF, RAISING TWO DAUGHTERS
AND THREE STEPDAUGHTERS.
FRIENDS AND PARENTS SAY
HOCHSPRUNG WAS PASSIONATE AND
DEDICATED, TOUGH BUT CARING AND
ONE SAID THE KIDS LOVED HER.
>> THE PRINCIPAL WHO, GOD BLESS
HER, LOST HER LIFE, WAS JUST A
VERY SPECIAL PERSON AND ALL THE
PARENTS KNEW THAT.
>> WOLF BLITZER, CNN, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> AT ONE POINT EARLIER TONIGHT,
A MAN STEPPED FORWARD BEFORE
CAMERAS TO PAY AN INCREDIBLY
LOVING TRIBUTE TO HIS OWN
DAUGHTER, EMILIE PARKER WAS JUST
6 YEARS OLD.
SHE WAS ONE OF THE LITTLE GIRLS
KILLED YESTERDAY.
HER FATHER, ROBBIE PARKER, SAID
HE IS EVEN PRAYING FOR THE
SHOOTER'S FAMILY TONIGHT, WATCH
>> I'D REALLY LIKE TO OFFER OUR
DEEPEST CONDOLENCES TO THE
FAMILIES WHO WERE DIRECTLY
AFFECTED BY THIS SHOOTING.
IT'S AN HORRIFIC TRAGEDY AND WE
WANT EVERYBODY TO KNOW THAT OUR
HEARTS AND OUR PRAYERS GO OUT TO
THEM.
THIS INCLUDES THE FAMILY OF THE
SHOOTER.
I CAN'T IMAGINE HOW HARD THIS
EXPERIENCE MUST BE FOR YOU AND I
WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT OUR FAMILY
AND OUR LOVE AND OUR SUPPORT
GOES OUT TO YOU AS WELL.
MY DAUGHTER, EMILIE, WOULD BE
ONE OF THE FIRST ONES TO BE
STANDING AND GIVING HER LOVE AND
SUPPORT TO ALL THOSE VICTIMS
BECAUSE THAT'S THE TYPE OF
PERSON THAT SHE IS, NOT BECAUSE
OF ANY PARENTING THAT MY WIFE
AND I COULD HAVE DONE, BUT
BECAUSE THOSE WERE THE GIFTS
THAT WERE GIVEN TO HER BY HER
HEAVENLY FATHER.
I HAVE TWO REALLY GOOD FRIENDS
AT HOME WHO HAVE SET UP A
FACEBOOK PAGE TO HELP RAISE
MONEY FOR EMILIE.
WHEN I'VE GOTTEN ON THAT AND
SEEN THE NUMBER OF PEOPLE WHO
HAVE COMMENTED AND EXPRESSED
THEIR CONDOLENCES, IT'S BEEN
QUITE OVERWHELMING.
AS THE DEEP PAIN BEGINS TO
SETTLE INTO OUR HEARTS, WE FIND
COMFORT REFLECTING ON THE
INCREDIBLE PERSON THAT EMILIE
WAS AND HOW MANY LIVES THAT SHE
WAS ABLE TO TOUCH IN HER SHORT
TIME HERE ON EARTH.
EMILIE WAS BRIGHT, CREATIVE AND
VERY LOVING.
EMILIE WAS ALWAYS WILLING TO TRY
NEW THINGS, OTHER THAN FOOD.
SHE LOVED TO USE HER TALENTS TO
TOUCH THE LIVES OF EVERYONE THAT
SHE CAME INTO CONTACT WITH.
SHE WAS AN EXCEPTIONAL ARTIST
AND SHE ALWAYS CARRIED AROUND
HER MARKERS AND PENCILS SO SHE
NEVER MISSED AN OPPORTUNITY TO
DRAW A PICTURE OR MAKE A CARD
FOR THOSE AROUND HER.
I CAN'T COUNT THE NUMBER OF
TIMES EMILIE NOTICED SOMEONE
FEELING SAD OR FRUSTRATED AND
WOULD RUSH TO FIND A PIECE OF
PAPER TO DRAW THEM A PICTURE OR
TO WRITE THEM AN ENCOURAGING
NOTE.
EMILIE'S CARD MAKING WAS
EXPRESSED BEAUTIFULLY THIS LAST
OCTOBER WHEN SHE PLACED A VERY
SPECIAL CARD SHE HAD MADE INTO
THE CASKET WITH HER GRANDPA, WHO
ALSO JUST RECENTLY DIED OF A
TRAGIC ACCIDENT.
EMILIE WAS A MENTOR TO HER TWO
LITTLE SISTERS AND DELIGHTED IN
TEACHING THEM HOW TO READ, DANCE
AND FIND THE SIMPLE JOYS IN
LIFE.
EMILIE'S LAUGHTER WAS INFECTIOUS
AND ALL THOSE WHO HAD THE
PLEASURE TO MEET HER WOULD AGREE
THAT THIS WORLD IS A BETTER
PLACE BECAUSE SHE'S BEEN IN IT.
SHE WAS THEIR BEST FRIEND.
THEY WERE ALL BORN WITHIN THREE
YEARS OF EACH OTHER SO BY LAW,
THEY'RE VERY CLOSE.
SHE WAS TEACHING MY MIDDLE
DAUGHTER TO READ.
SHE WOULD HELP MY YOUNGEST
DAUGHTER LEARN HOW TO MAKE
THINGS, SHOW HER HOW TO DO
CRAFTS.
THEY LOOKED UP TO HER AND THEY
LOOKED TO HER WHEN THEY NEEDED
COMFORT.
USUALLY THAT'S SAVED FOR A MOM
AND A DAD.
BUT IT WAS REALLY SWEET TO SEE
THE TIMES WHEN ONE OF THEM WOULD
FALL OR GET THEIR FEELINGS HURT,
HOW THEY WOULD RUN TO EMILIE TO
GET SUPPORT AND HUGS AND KISSES.
SHE WAS THE TYPE OF PERSON THAT
COULD JUST LIGHT UP A ROOM.
SHE ALWAYS HAD SOMETHING KIND TO
SAY ABOUT ANYBODY.
AND HER LOVE AND THE STRENGTH
THAT SHE GAVE US AND THE EXAMPLE
THAT SHE SHOWED TO US IS
REMARKABLE.
SHE IS AN INCREDIBLE PERSON.
AND I'M SO BLESSED TO BE HER
DAD.
I WAS LEAVING TO WORK AND SHE
WOKE UP BEFORE I LEFT.
AND I'VE ACTUALLY BEEN TEACHING
HER PORTUGUESE.
SO OUR LAST CONVERSATION WAS IN
PORTUGUESE.
AND SHE TOLD ME GOOD MORNING.
ASKED HOW I WAS DOING.
I SAID THAT I WAS DOING WELL.
SHE SAID THAT SHE LOVED ME.
I GAVE HER A KISS AND I WAS OUT
THE DOOR.
FREE AGENCY IS GIVEN TO ALL OF
US TO ACT AND DO WHAT WE WANT.
GOD CAN'T TAKE THAT AWAY FROM
US.
I KNOW THAT THAT'S SOMETHING
THAT HE WAS GIVEN AND THAT'S
WHAT HE CHOSE TO DO WITH IT.
I KNOW THAT GOD CAN'T TAKE THAT
AWAY.
I'M NOT MAD BECAUSE I HAVE MY
AGENCY TO MAKE SURE THAT I USE
THIS EVENT TO DO WHAT I CAN TO
DO WHATEVER I CAN.
TO WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT MY
FAMILY AND MY WIFE AND MY
DAUGHTERS ARE TAKEN CARE OF AND
THAT IF THERE'S ANYTHING THAT I
CAN DO TO HELP ANYBODY AT ANY
TIME, ANYWHERE, I'D BE WILLING
TO DO THAT.
AS WE MOVE ON FROM WHAT HAPPENED
HERE, WHAT HAPPENED TO SO MANY
PEOPLE, LET IT NOT TURN INTO
SOMETHING THAT DEFINES US, BUT
SOMETHING THAT INSPIRES US TO BE
BETTER, TO BE MORE COMPASSIONATE
AND MORE HUMBLE PEOPLE.
>> A FATHER IN MOURNING SPEAKING
OF COMPASSION FOR OTHERS.
WHAT HAPPENED AT THAT SCHOOL IS
SADLY JUST THE LATEST ON A LONG
LIST OF VIOLENT ATTACKS WITH
GUNS OVER THE YEARS.
WHEN WE FIRST HEARD WHAT
HAPPENED IN CONNECTICUT, PEOPLE
PROBABLY THOUGHT ABOUT THE OTHER
DEADLY SHOOTINGS.
PLACES LIKE VIRGINIA TECH OR
COLUMBINE
JOINING ME NOW IS PASTOR ROCKY
VEACH WHO WAS LIVING NEAR
LITTLETON, COLORADO, WHEN THE
COLUMBINE SITUATION OCCURRED.
HE NOW LIVES HERE IN CONNECTICUT
WHAT DO YOU SAY FOR FAMILIES WHO
COME TO YOU AND PEOPLE IN THIS
COMMUNITY WHO WEREN'T EVEN
HAVING A LOVED ONE AT THAT
SCHOOL BUT WHO JUST -- EVERYBODY
FEELS AFFECTED.
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
>> YEAH, AS A CHRISTIAN, WHAT
CAN YOU SAY TO START WITH?
BUT AS A CHRISTIAN, YOU TELL
THEM, THERE'S HOPE IN THE LORD.
GOD KNOWS WHERE YOU'RE AT.
GOD CARES FOR YOU AND LOVES YOU.
RATHER THAN SAYING A LOT ABOUT
JESUS, TRYING TO BE LIKE JESUS.
THAT IS WHAT I'M TRYING TO DO
>> IT SEEMS, TOO, A LOT OF TIMES
JUST BEING THERE IS IMPORTANT
AND LISTENING IS AS IMPORTANT AS
WHAT YOU SAY.
>> YEAH, VERY MUCH SO.
THAT'S WHAT ANYBODY NEEDS IN
THIS KIND OF SETTING.
AND HAVING BEEN IN THIS SETTING
A TIME BEFORE, AND ACTUALLY I'M
GLAD TO BE AROUND TO BE ABLE TO
HELP PEOPLE HERE.
>> YOU FEEL LIKE YOU'RE IN THE
RIGHT PLACE AT THE RIGHT TIME.
>> YEAH, RIGHT PLACE AT THE
RIGHT TIME.
AND THE CHURCH THAT I PASTOR, I
THINK THEY FEEL THAT WAY, TOO.
WE'VE BEEN CONDUCTING PRAYER
MEETINGS IN THE AREA, PRAYING
FOR PEOPLE.
AND GETTING IN TOUCH WITH GOD
AND ASKING HIM TO HELP THEM AND
HELP USE US IN WAYS THAT CAN BE
HELPFUL TOWARD OTHER PEOPLE.
>> IT IS EXTRAORDINARY -- I'VE
SPENT A LITTLE BIT OF TIME IN
THIS TOWN.
JUST TO SEE HOW PEOPLE ARE
COMING TOGETHER.
PEOPLE ARE STOPPING HERE, PEOPLE
ARE STOPPING DOWN THE STREET AND
JUST KIND OF TALKING TO ONE
ANOTHER, COMPLETE STRANGERS KIND
OF REACHING OUT TO ONE ANOTHER
IN GRIEF AND IN SADNESS.
>> YEAH, I THINK IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
I THINK IT'S SOMETHING IN ALL OF
US THAT CAN HELP ALLEVIATE THE
PAIN WHEN WE GO THROUGH A CRISIS
SITUATION.
WE NEED EACH OTHER AND THAT'S
ONE OF THE BEAUTIFUL THINGS
ABOUT COMMUNITY.
>> DO YOU ENCOURAGE PEOPLE TO
TALK ABOUT IT?
I LOST A BROTHER YEARS AGO TO
SUICIDE.
AND MY MOM FOUND IT HELPFUL TO
TALK ABOUT IT OVER AND OVER
AGAIN.
AND I FOUND IT VERY, VERY
DIFFICULT AND EVEN STILL TO THIS
DAY.
DO YOU ENCOURAGE PEOPLE TO TALK?
>> I ENCOURAGE PEOPLE TO TALK
ABOUT IT.
AND I ENCOURAGE PEOPLE TO TALK
TO THE LORD ABOUT IT.
SOMETIMES WE FORGET THAT WE CAN
TALK TO GOD, TALK TO HIM
DIRECTLY.
AND HE UNDERSTANDS IN A WAY THAT
A PERSON REALLY CAN'T.
AGAIN, EVERYTHING I'M ABOUT IS
LOOKING TO HIM.
>> THERE ARE NO DOUBT PEOPLE WHO
WITNESS WHAT HAPPENED AND
QUESTION FAITH, QUESTION HOW CAN
THIS HAPPEN -- HOW CAN THIS BE
ALLOWED TO HAPPEN?
HOW DO YOU ANSWER?
>> THAT'S THE AGE-OLD QUESTION.
I LOOK AT EVIL -- TO BELIEVE IN
EVIL, YOU HAVE TO BELIEVE IN
GOOD.
I GO BACK TO THE STORY OF
CREATION.
GOD'S THE CREATOR AND THERE IS
AN ADVERSARY, THERE IS AN ENEMY.
GOD'S NOT THE AUTHOR OF THIS.
THE BIBLE SAYS THAT GOD IS THE
AUTHOR OF ABUNDANT LIFE.
THE DEVIL IS THE AUTHOR OF THIS
KIND OF LIFE.
HE COMES TO STEAL, KILL AND
DESTROY.
IT'S SAD.
BUT GOD IS BIGGER THAN THAT.
THAT'S WHY WE POINT PEOPLE
TOWARDS HIM IN THIS KIND OF
SCENARIO.
>> AND FAITH GETS YOU THROUGH?
>> FAITH GETS YOU THROUGH.
I THINK PEOPLE FIND THAT FAITH
GETS THEM THROUGH A LOT OF
THINGS THAT YOU MIGHT NOT THINK
IT WILL AT THE TIME.
HAVING LIVED IN COLUMBINE, I SAW
THIS ONCE BEFORE -- OR IN DENVER
DURING COLUMBINE, SAW THIS ONCE
BEFORE.
IT'S AMAZING.
CHANGED MY LIFE WATCHING HOW
OTHER PEOPLE -- HOW GOD DID HELP
THEM AND DID GET THEM THROUGH
TIMES WHEN THEY THOUGHT THEY
WOULDN'T MAKE IT THROUGH.
>> AND TO SEE PARENTS -- TO SEE
MR. PARKER SPEAKING ABOUT HIS
DAUGHTER, THE STRENGTH THAT
TAKES, THE STRENGTH THAT TAKES
JUST TO GET THROUGH MINUTE BY
MINUTE, SECOND BY SECOND.
>> YEAH.
NO, THAT WAS VERY TOUCHING
THERE.
IT'S JUST A HORRIBLE SCENARIO, A
HORRIBLE SITUATION.
LIKE WE SAID IN THE BEGINNING,
WORDS CAN'T REALLY DO ANYTHING
IN THIS.
HOW CAN I UNDERSTAND HIM?
I JUST TRY TO LOVE HIM AND BE
THERE FOR HIM AND PEOPLE LIKE
HIM, BE THERE IN THE COMMUNITY.
>> SOMETIMES THE WORDS SEEM --
THEY FEEL SO SMALL IN A
SITUATION LIKE THIS.
PASTOR, APPRECIATE YOU BEING ON.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> THERE'S STILL A LOT FOR US TO
LEARN IN THE DAYS AHEAD AND AS
OUR COVERAGE CONTINUES.
WE'LL TAKE A SHORT BREAK.
WE'LL CONTINUE REMEMBERING THE
VICTIMS TONIGHT WHEN WE COME
BACK.
[ Male Announcer ] Alka-Seltzer
Plus PRESENTS THE Cold Truth.
I HAVE A COLD,
AND I TOOK NYQUIL,
BUT I'M STILL "STUBBED" UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT DOESN'T HAVE A DECONGESTANT.
NO WAY.
[ Male Announcer ] SORRY.
Alka-Seltzer Plus FIGHTS
YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A FAST ACTING
DECONGESTANT
TO RELIEVE YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
[ sighs ] THANKS!
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus.
♪ OH
WHAT A RELIEF IT IS! ♪
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
AND SAVE $1
VISIT Alka-Seltzer ON FACEBOOK.
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
I HAVE OBLIGATIONS. CUTE
TOBLIGATIONS, BUT OBLIGATIONS.G.
I NEED TO RETHINK THE
CORE OF MY PORTFOLIO.
WHAT I REALLY NEED IS SLEEP.
INTRODUCING THE ISHARES CORE,
BUILDING BLOCKS FOR THE
HEART OF YOUR PORTFOLIO.
FIND OUT WHY 9 OUT OF 10
LARGE PROFESSIONAL INVESTORS
CHOOSE ISHARES FOR THEIR ETFS.
ISHARES BY BLACKROCK.
CALL 1-800-ISHARES FOR A
PROSPECTUS WHICH INCLUDES
INVESTMENT OBJECTIVES,
RISKS, CHARGES AND EXPENSES.
READ AND CONSIDER
IT CAREFULLY
BEFORE INVESTING.
RISK INCLUDES POSSIBLE
LOSS OF PRINCIPAL.
TRAGIC SCENE FOR EVERYBODY.
CERTAINLY OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN
FOR THE FAMILIES HERE.
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, ABOUT 9:30,
9:40, WE HEARD NOISES.
AND THE ANNOUNCEMENT SYSTEM WAS
STILL ON.
SO IT DIDN'T GO OFF.
SO YOU COULD HEAR WHAT SOUNDED
LIKE POPS, GUNSHOTS.
>> HER TEACHER MANAGED TO TAKE
TWO CHILDREN OUT OF THE HALLWAY,
PULL THEM INTO THE CLASSROOM,
LOCK THE DOOR AND MOVE EVERYBODY
OVER TO THE OTHER SIDE OF THE
ROOM.
>> WE JUST TOLD A LITTLE BOY
ABOUT HIS SISTER NOW.
HE SAID, WHO AM I GOING TO PLAY
WITH NOW?
I HAVE NOBODY TO PLAY WITH NOW.
EXCUSE ME.
>> WHEN YOUR FIRST-GRADER GOES
TO BED AND SAYS, MOMMY, IS
ANYONE FROM MY CLASS LAST
YEAR -- ARE THEY ALL OKAY?
AND YOU LOOK AT THEM AND SAY,
I'M NOT REALLY SURE.
>> YOU CAN NEVER BE PREPARED FOR
THIS KIND OF INCIDENT.
WHAT HAS HAPPENED, WHAT HAS
TRANSPIRED AT THAT SCHOOL
BUILDING WILL LEAVE A MARK ON
THIS COMMUNITY AND EVERY FAMILY
IMPACTED.
>> AS I'VE BEEN SAYING SINCE THE
BEGINNING OF OUR COVERAGE, WE
WANT TO REALLY FOCUS ON THE
VICTIMS, ON THE LIVES THEY
LIVED.
AND WE WANT TODAY TO TRY TO
LEARN AS MUCH AS WE CAN ABOUT
THEM AND IN THE DAYS AHEAD, TO
THEM AS WHEN THEIR FAMILIES WANT
THAT INFORMATION OUT.
AT THIS POINT, WE DON'T HAVE
PICTURES OF MANY OF THE VICTIMS.
WE'RE WAITING OF COURSE FOR
FAMILIES TO RELEASE THAT IF AND
WHEN THEY CHOOSE TO.
BUT WE DO HAVE THEIR NAMES
TONIGHT.
AND I JUST WANT TO TAKE A FEW
MOMENTS AND JUST READ YOU THEIR
NAMES SO THAT YOU REMEMBER THEIR
NAMES.
SO OFTEN WE REMEMBER THE NAMES
OF THE SHOOTERS IN THESE KIND OF
SITUATIONS.
I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT TO
REMEMBER THE NAMES OF THE
VICTIMS INSTEAD.
CHARLOTTE BACON WAS JUST 6 YEARS
OLD.
WE REMEMBER HER TONIGHT.
DANIEL BARDEN WAS 7 YEARS OLD.
WE REMEMBER HIM TONIGHT.
RACHEL DAVINO, TEACHER, WAS 29
YEARS OLD.
WE REMEMBER HER.
OLIVIA ENGEL, 6 YEARS OLD.
OUR THOUGHTS ARE WITH HER
FAMILY.
JOSEPHINE GAY WAS 7 YEARS OLD.
SHE JUST HAD A BIRTHDAY ON
TUESDAY.
ANA MARQUEZ GREEN WAS 6 YEARS
OLD.
DYLAN HOCKLEY, 6 YEARS OLD.
PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG 47
YEARS OLD.
MADELEINE WAS 6 YEARS OLD.
CATHERINE HUBBARD WAS 6 YEARS
OLD AS WELL.
CHASE WAS 6 YEARS OLD.
JESSE LOUIS, JESSE WAS SIX YEARS
OLD, AS WELL
JAMES WAS 6 YEARS OLD AS WELL.
GRACE McDONNELL, 7 YEARS OLD.
ANNE MARIE MURPHY, SHE WAS A
TEACHER, 52 YEARS OLD.
EMILIE PARKER, SHE WAS 6 YEARS
OLD.
JACK PINTO, ALSO 6.
NOAH POZNER WAS 6 YEARS OLD.
CAROLINE WAS 6 YEARS OLD AS
WELL.
JESSICA WAS 6.
AVIELLE RICHMAN WAS ALSO 6.
SHE WAS KILLED YESTERDAY.
LAUREN WAS A SUBSTITUTE TEACHER,
30 YEARS OLD.
MAIR SHERLACH, THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST, SHE WAS 56.
TEACHER VICTORIA SOTO WAS 27.
BENJAMIN WHEELER WAS 6 YEARS
OLD.
AND ALLISON WYATT WAS 6 YEARS
OLD AS WELL.
WE REMEMBER THEM ALL TONIGHT AND
IN THE DAYS, THE WEEKS AND
HOPEFULLY THE YEARS AHEAD.
A VIGIL IN MAIN STREET HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A SHORT
BREAK AND BE BACK IN A MOMENT.
>>> THE SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN IS
NOW THE SECOND DEADLIEST SCHOOL
SHOOTING IN U.S. HISTORY BEHIND
THE VIRGINIA TECH MASSACRE IN
2007.
AFTER EVERY EVENT LIKE THIS, THE
QUESTIONS ALWAYS ARE THE SAME,
WHAT CAUSES THIS KIND OF A
SHOOTING?
HOW CAN THIS HAPPEN?
HOW CAN THEY BE STOPPED?
I'M JOINED NOW BY KATHERINE
NEWMAN FROM BALTIMORE WHO WROTE
THE BOOK "RAMPAGE, THE SOCIAL
ROOTS OF SCHOOL SHOOTINGS" SHE'S
STUDIED MANY OF THESE KINDS OF
EVENTS.
CATHERINE, I REALLY APPRECIATE
YOU BEING WITH US AND I HAVE
READ A LITTLE YOUR RESEARCH
WHAT HAVE YOU LEARNED ABOUT
THESE SHOOTINGS THAT ARE SORT OF
COUNTERINTUITIVE?
PEOPLE THINK THEY KNOW WHAT
CAUSES THEM AT TIMES ABOUT THE
COLUMBINE.
BUT SO MANY OF THE THINGS WE
THOUGHT WE KNEW ABOUT COLUMBINE
HAVE TURNED OUT NOT TO BE TRUE.
WHAT DO WE NOW KNOW ABOUT WHAT
CAUSES THESE KINDS OF EVENTS?
>> THAT'S SO TRUE.
OFTEN WHAT WE LEARNED IN THE
BEGINNING TURN OUT TO BE DEAD
WRONG
SOME OF THE COMMON MYTHS ARE
THAT THESE THINGS ARE
SPONTANEOUS.
THEY'RE ALMOST NEVER
SOME OF THE SHOOTINGS WE STUDIED
WERE PLANNED OVER A NINE-MONTH
PERIOD.
OFTEN WITH THEY THAT NOBODY
KNOWS ABOUT WHAT IS COMING, BUT
SADLY, THERE ARE QUITE A FEW
PEOPLE WHO HAVE AN INKLING
IN SOME OF THE SCHOOL SHOOTINGS
WE STUDIED, THERE WERE CHILDREN
WHO DIDN'T COME TO SCHOOL THAT
DAY BECAUSE THEY WERE WORRIED
SOMETHING WAS GOING TO HAPPEN
BUT SADLY THEY NEVER TOLD ANYONE
WHO COULD HAVE DONE ANYTHING.
AND SO ONE OF THE
COUNTERINTUITIVE THINGS WE
LEARNED WAS THAT THERE'S A LOT
OF INFORMATION OFTEN CIRCULATING
BUT IT DOESN'T GET TO THE RIGHT
PLACE.
IT DOESN'T MEAN THAT WAS TRUE IN
THIS PARTICULAR INSTANCE.
IT WILL TAKE TIME BEFORE WE KNOW
ENOUGH TO GENERALIZE TO IT.
BUT IN THE STUDIES WE STUDIED --
AND WE STUDIED ALL OF THEM FROM
THE 1970s ONWARD IN THE UNITED
STATES, IT WAS FREQUENTLY THE
CASE THAT THERE WAS A LOT OF
KNOWLEDGE IN PEER COMMUNITIES
THAT DIDN'T GET THROUGH TO THE
ADULTS IN TIME TO DO ANYTHING
ABOUT IT.
IT'S ALSO THE CASE THAT IT
FREQUENTLY HAPPENS IN TOWNS JUST
LIKE NEWTOWN, SMALL, RURAL
SETTINGS, NOT THE PLACES THAT WE
THINK OF AS CHARACTERISTICALLY
VIOLENT.
WE THINK OF BIG CITIES AS PLACES
WHERE THERE'S GUN VIOLENCE.
AND OF COURSE THERE IS.
BUT THESE KINDS OF SHOOTINGS
DON'T HAPPEN IN BIG CITIES.
THEY HAPPEN USUALLY IN SMALL
TOWNS OR SUBURBS.
>> AND IS THERE A COMMON THREAD
IN THE MENTAL HEALTH HISTORY OF
THE BOYS INVOLVED IN THESE?
>> THERE IS ALMOST ALWAYS A
MENTAL HEALTH CONDITION.
THE SAD THING IS IT'S OFTEN
UNRECOGNIZED AND UNTREATED.
SO WE DON'T KNOW IF THAT WILL BE
TRUE IN THIS CASE.
BUT IN MOST OF THE CASES WE
LOOKED AT, THERE WAS
AFTER-THE-FACT EVIDENCE OF
MENTAL DISORDERS BUT NO
TREATMENT.
OR HAD EVER BEEN DIAGNOSED
THAT'S DISTURBING BECAUSE WE
LIKE TO THINK WE CAN RECOGNIZE
THE SYMPTOMS.
BUT PARTICULARLY WHEN THE
SHOOTERS ARE YOUNGER THAN THIS
ONE, THE ONES WE LOOKED AT WERE
13, 12, THE SIGNS OF
DISTINGUISHED MENTAL ILLNESS
THAT ARE GOING TO BE SO VIVID IF
THEY SURVIVE INTO THEIR 20s ARE
NOT SO EASY TO DISCERN WHEN
THEY'RE 13.
SO SADLY THERE IS A -- THERE'S
EVIDENCE AFTER THE FACT OFTEN
THAT COMES UP IN FORENSIC
EXAMINATIONS, BUT NOT THE KIND
OF EVIDENCE THAT LEADS TO THE
TREATMENT THAT THEY SO
DESPERATELY NEED.
>> IT'S ALSO INTERESTING IN THE
BOOK TITLE, YOU TALK ABOUT THE
SOCIAL ROOTS OF THESE SHOOTINGS.
OFTENTIMES THE IDEAS THAT THESE
ARE LONERS ON THE FRINGE.
BUT YOU'VE FOUND IT'S NOT THAT
SIMPLE.
>> NO.
SADLY THEY ARE RARELY LONERS.
IT'S MORE CHARACTERISTIC TO SAY
THEY'RE FAILED JOINERS.
THEY ARE PEOPLE WHO HAVE
TYPICALLY TRIED TO JOIN GROUPS
AND ARE REBUFFED AND REJECTED.
SO THEIR EXPERIENCE IS NOT THAT
OF BEING A LONER.
IT'S OF BEING PUSHED ASIDE AND
MADE TO FEEL REJECTED.
AND SO WHAT TYPICALLY HAPPENS
WITH THESE YOUNG MEN IS THAT
THEY GO THROUGH A WHOLE SERIES
OF EFFORTS TO TRY AND GET
ATTENTION AND INGRATIATE
THEMSELVES IN GROUPS.
ALL THOSE EFFORTS FAIL AND THEY
START TALKING ABOUT SHOOTING
PEOPLE AND SUDDENLY EVERYONE'S
PAYING ATTENTION.
SO THEY'RE TRYING TO CHANGE HOW
PEOPLE THINK ABOUT THEM AND
NOTORIOUS AND EVIL SEEMS BETTER
TO THEM THAN A LOSER.
>> IT'S ONE OF THE REASONS I
BELIEVE JUST IN NOT TRYING TO
MENTION THEIR NAMES BECAUSE JUST
THE IDEA THAT SOMEBODY CAN
BELIEVE THAT THEY CAN GAME FAME
OR NOTORIETY BY DOING THIS, I
JUST DON'T THINK IT'S GOOD TO
PERPETUATE THAT.
I KIND YOUR RESEARCH REALLY
FASCINATING.
I'D LOOV TO TALK TO YOU MORE IN
THE DAYS AHEAD.
THANKS FOR BEING WITH US.
>> MY PLEASURE, ANDERSON.
>> SOME MEMORIES ARE SEARED INTO
OUR MINDS NO MATTER HOW MUCH ONE
WANTS TO FORGET THEM.
THE NEWTOWN SHOOTING NO DOUBT
FALLS INTO THAT CATEGORY FOR ONE
OF THE SCHOOL'S TEACHERS.
YET IN THE MIDST OF A CRISIS,
SHE STAYED REMARKABLY CALM FOR
HER KINDERGARTEN STUDENTS.
I TALKED TO HER, JANET VOLLMER
IS HER NAME.
I WANT YOU TO HEAR WHAT SHE SAID
ABOUT HOW SHE GOT HERSELF
THROUGH THIS CRISIS.
LISTEN.
>> ABOUT 9:30, 9:40, WE HEARD
NOISES.
AND THE ANNOUNCEMENT SYSTEM WAS
STILL ON.
SO IT DIDN'T GO OFF.
SO YOU COULD HEAR WHAT SOUNDED
LIKE POPS, GUNSHOTS.
OF COURSE I'M NOT GOING TO TELL
THAT TO 5-YEAR-OLDS.
SO I SAID TO THEM, WE'RE GOING
OVER IN A SAFE AREA AND WE'RE
GOING TO -- WE READ A STORY AND
WE KEPT THEM CALM.
DID A LOCKDOWN DRILL, CLOSED THE
DOORS, LOCKED -- COVERED THE
WINDOWS.
KEPT THE CHILDREN WITH US.
I HAVE OTHER ADULTS --
>> I FIND THAT AMAZING THAT
FEARING THAT YOU HEAR GUNSHOTS,
YOU WERE ABLE TO HAVE THE
COMPOSURE TO SIT DOWN AND READ
TO YOUR STUDENTS.
THAT'S EXTRAORDINARY.
>> THAT'S WHAT YOU HAVE TO DO
WITH 5-YEAR-OLDS BECAUSE YOU
CAN'T LOSE IT.
I'VE BEEN DOING THIS FOR A LONG
TIME.
IT'S MY 18th YEAR OF TEACHING.
MY JOB WAS TO KEEP THEM SAFE.
I DIDN'T KNOW -- THERE WAS NO
ANNOUNCEMENT OF WHAT WAS GOING
ON.
MY INSTINCT WAS IT WASN'T GOOD.
SO WE KEPT THEM CALM.
WE STAYED IN THE ROOM UNTIL
THERE WAS BANGING AT THE DOOR,
WHICH WERE THE POLICE AND THE
TROOPERS OR WHOEVER WAS THERE.
THEY HAD US EXIT THE BUILDING.
THEY TOLD THE CHILDREN TO COVER
THEIR EYES AND WALK IN A LINE
AND LEAVE THE BUILDING AND
THAT'S WHEN WE WENT DOWN TOWARDS
THE FIREHOUSE.
WE WERE ALL SAFE.
I HAD 19 CHILDREN IN THE ROOM
WITH ME AND THANK GOODNESS ALL
OF THEIR PARENTS WERE ABLE TO
COME AND PICK THEM UP AND TAKE
THEM HOME.
>> AS YOU WERE READING TO THEM,
DID THE KIDS REALIZE SOMETHING
WAS GOING ON OR DID THEY JUST
THINK IT WAS A DRILL LIKE YOU'D
HAD BEFORE?
>> RIGHT.
IT DIDN'T SEEM A NATURAL THING.
ALTHOUGH WE DO PRACTICE DRILLS.
WE JUST SAID, WELL, WE'RE NOT
REALLY SURE BUT WE'RE GOING TO
BE SAFE BECAUSE WE'RE SITTING
OVER HERE AND WE'RE ALL
TOGETHER.
AND THAT'S AS WE GOT DOWN TO THE
FIREHOUSE LATER ON, AS A LOT OF
THE EVENTS STARTED TO UNFOLD
THROUGHOUT THE DAY, I THINK SOME
OF THEM REALIZED THE MAGNITUDE
OF WHAT WAS GOING ON.
THEY SAW OTHER PEOPLE UPSET.
BUT WE JUST HELD THEM CLOSE
UNTIL THEIR PARENTS CAME AND WE
RELEASED THEM.
MY ROOM, MY CHILDREN WERE ALL
ACCOUNTED FOR AND SAFE IN MY
KINDERGARTEN CLASSROOM
>> WE TALKED ABOUT SOME OF THE
KIDS DEALING WITH THE POTENTIAL
FOR PTSD.
ALSO FIRST RESPONDERS DEALING
WITH THE STRESS IN ALL OF THIS
AND WHAT THEY'VE HAD TO SEE.
TERRY LYLES DEALS WITH STRESS
AND CRISIS MANAGEMENT.
HE JOINS ME FROM MIAMI.
IT IS EASY TO FORGET THESE
SCENES ARE PROBABLY THE WORST
MANY OF THESE EMERGENCY WORKERS
HAVE EVER WITNESSED.
I CAN'T IMAGINE THE THINGS THEY
SAW IN THOSE SCHOOLS -- IN THAT
SCHOOL.
YOU HELP RESCUE WORKERS DEAL
WITH TRAGEDY FOLLOWING THE
SEPTEMBER 11th ATTACKS.
WHAT'S YOUR ADVICE?
HOW DO YOU HELP THEM?
>> WELL, ANDERSON, THANK YOU FOR
HAVING ME.
I THINK THE BIGGEST THING THAT
WE HAVE TO REMEMBER IS THAT THE
CLOSEST YOU ARE TO THE
EPICENTER, HEARING THE SHOTS,
SEEING THE VIOLENCE VISUALLY,
THE MORE YOU'RE GOING TO NEED TO
BE ABLE TO DEBRIEF.
AS I DEBRIEF SPECIAL FORCES
PEOPLE AND SOLDIERS, IT'S VERY
IMPORTANT THAT THESE CHILDREN,
THEIR PARENTS UNDERSTAND THAT
THERE'S LIFE AFTER TRAGEDY BUT
WE HAVE TO LISTEN TO THEIR
STORIES, WE HAVE TO HELP THEM
VENT AND RELEASE THAT
INFORMATION THAT THEY CAN
NORMALIZE AND GO BACK TO SOME
TYPE OF LIFE AS THEY KNEW IT
BEFORE THIS TRAGIC DAY.
>> WHAT KIND OF SYMPTOMS DO
PARENTS, DO FRIENDS OF PEOPLE
NEED TO LOOK OUT FOR?
>> WELL, TYPICALLY WITH
CHILDREN, IT'S ALL AGE
APPROPRIATENESS.
SO IT REALLY DEPENDS.
BUT USUALLY SLEEP CAN BE
DISRUPTED.
THERE CAN BE NIGHTMARES.
THERE COULD BE SUDDEN NOISES
THAT COULD STARTLE THEM.
MOODINESS THAT YOU'VE NOT SEEN
BEFORE, MAYBE A LOSS IN APPETITE
OR A LOSS OF INTEREST IN NORMAL
THINGS.
AND I THINK FOR PARENTS MAINLY,
WE'RE ALL JUST MORTIFIED BY THIS
EVENT.
AND I THINK AS PARENTS WE HAVE
TO MAKE SURE THAT WE'RE TALKING
TO OUR CHILDREN, REGARDLESS OF
WHERE WE ARE IN THE COUNTRY OR
AROUND THE WORLD, THAT WE CAN
LET OUR CHILDREN KNOW AND
SUPPORT THEM TO SAY, LISTEN,
IT'S OKAY, THIS DOESN'T HAPPEN
ON A REGULAR BASIS.
THIS WAS NOT A NORMAL SITUATION
AND WE HAVE TO SUPPORT THEM AND
CARE FOR THEM THAT THEY KNOW
THAT THEY'RE SECURED IN A NORMAL
WORLD THAT WE LIVE IN.
>> BUT TALKING ABOUT IT HELPS?
>> WELL, AGAIN, IT DEPENDS ON
THE AGE.
THE AGES OF THE KIDS THAT YOU
MENTIONED, I AGREE WITH YOU.
I THINK IT'S VERY DIFFICULT TO
BE ABLE TO EVEN NAME THE NAMES
AND THE AGES OF THESE CHILDREN.
IT'S HEARTBREAKING.
AND I THINK WHAT HE CAN DO, AS
WE TALK TO OUR CHILDREN, IF
CHILDREN CAN DRAW PICTURES AND
WRITE LETTERS IF THAT'S WHAT IT
GOES, TO FRIENDS THAT THEY LOST
OR THE SITUATIONS THEY HEARD AND
DESTROY THOSE LETTERS.
WE DESTROY EVERYTHING THAT IS OF
WASTE TO US.
WE PUT GARBAGE BAGS OUT.
WE FLUSH GARBAGE DISPOSALS.
IT'S THE SAME WAY WITH THE
EMOTIONAL WASTE.
WE HAVE TO HELP THEM VENT AND
PROCESS, RELEASE IT AND LET THEM
KNOW AS WE TALK TO THEM THAT
THEY HAVE A REFUGE WITHIN US AND
THAT WE AS PARENTS ARE THERE TO
SUPPORT THEM THROUGH THIS
SITUATION.
>> TERRY LYLES, I APPRECIATE
YOUR EXPERTISE.