JESUS [ BLEEP ] CHRIST.
I COME ON THE NEWS FOR TWO
SECONDS AND YOU WANT TO -- EVERY
TIME I DO AN INTERVIEW, I GUY
WANTS TO OPEN HIS [ BLEEP ]
MOUTH.
CAN'T YOU [ BLEEP ] A ROUTINE
HERE.
GO [ BLEEP ] YOURSELF, YOU KNOW
WHAT.
>> OH!
OH!
YEAH, HE WAS BEING INTERVIEWED
FOR SOME REASON ON THE DEFUNCT
CNN-FN BY ALLAN CHERNOFF WHO
WOULD HAVE BEEN BETTER OFF
TRYING TO HOLD ON TO A FISH
WHILE STANDING IN A BOAT.
NICE TRY, CNBC, BUT WE'RE
HOLDING OUT FOR MODERATE TO
EXTREME CURSING.
THAT DOES IT FOR US.
WE'LL SEE YOU IN ONE HOUR FROM
NOW.
ANOTHER EDITION AT 10:00 P.M.
EASTERN.
THANKS FOR WATCHING.
"PIERS MORGAN TONIGHT" STARTS
NOW.
>>> TONIGHT, TEAM OBAMA TAKES A
BIG HIT.
SUSAN RICE DROPS OUT OF THE
RUNNING FOR SECRETARY OF STATE
AFTER A BRUISING BATTLE WITH
CRITICS LIKE JOHN McCAIN.
>> SHE NOT ONLY GAVE WRONG
INFORMATION, BUT SHE GAVE THE
PARTY LINE.
>> NOW IS JOHN KERRY A LOCK FOR
STATE?
>>> AND THE OTHER BIG LATE STORY
IN WASHINGTON, SPEAKER BOEHNER
GOES TO THE WHITE HOUSE.
HOW CLOSE ARE THEY NOW TO A
DEAL?
RUDOLPH GIULIANI IS HERE TO SAY
A LOT ABOUT THESE THINGS.
I'LL ASK HIM IF AMERICA IS
GETTING MORE DANGEROUS IN THE
WAKE SOME OF VERY SHOCKING
HIGH-PROFILE GUN CRIME.
>>> HE WAS KNOWN AS ONE OF THE
WEST MEMPHIS THREE NOW DAMIAN
EKLES IS ADJUSTING TO LIFE AS A
FREE MAN.
>> I WAS IN A STATE OF EXTREME
SHOCK AND TRAUMA.
>> AND HOW HE SURVIVED 18 YEARS
ON DEATH ROW.
>> IT'S ABSOLUTELY NIGHTMARISH.
>> THIS IS "PIERS MORGAN
TONIGHT."
>>> GOOD EVENING, YOU'RE LOOKING
LIVE AT THE WHITE HOUSE WHERE
PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS HAD ONE OF
THOSE WIN SOME, LOSE SOME KIND
OF DAYS.
THE PRESIDENT AND JOHN BOEHNER
MET FOR 50 MINUTES IN A MEETING
BEING CALLED FRANK.
WHEN BASICALLY TRANSLATES TO NO
DEAL YET.
BUT THE GOOD NEWS WAS, QUOTE,
THE LINES OF COMMUNICATION
REMAIN OPEN.
THE BAD NEWS, AMBASSADOR SUSAN
RICE WAS WITHDRAWING FROM THE
SHORT LIST TO REPLACE HILLARY
CLINTON AS SECRETARY OF STATE.
>> I WITHDREW MY NAME BECAUSE I
THINK IT'S THE RIGHT THING FOR
THE COUNTRY RAAND I THINK IT'S E
RIGHT THING FOR THE PRESIDENT.
PUTTING THOSE THINGS TOGETHER,
THAT MAKES IT THE RIGHT THING
FOR ME AND MY FAMILY.
>> RUDOLPH GIULIANI.
YOU'VE BEEN PRETTY VOCAL ABOUT
SUSAN RICE.
WERE YOU SURPRISED IN THE END
THAT SHE FELL ON HER SWORD
TODAY?
>> NOT AT ALL.
IN FACT I DON'T SEE THAT AS BAD
NEWS FOR THE PRESIDENT.
I SEE THAT AS GOOD NEWS FOR THE
PRESIDENT, BECAUSE A BATTLE TO
GET HER CONFIRMED WOULD HAVE
OFFERED THE PERFECT OPPORTUNITY
TO OPEN UP THIS WHOLE BENGHAZI
THING, WHERE NO ANSWERS HAVE YET
BEEN GIVEN.
>> YOU WERE ON TELEVISION WITH
HER.
>> I WAS, I WAS.
>> ON THAT FATEFUL MORNING.
>> I WAS ON THE CANDY CROWLEY
SHOW WHEN SHE APPEARED, RIGHT
HERE IN THIS BUILDING.
WATCHED IT, HAD MY LITTLE PAD IN
FRONT OF ME.
WHEN SHE SAID IT -- HONESTLY,
WHEN SHE SAID IT, I UTTERED AN
EXPRESSION THAT I CAN'T SAY ON
TELEVISION.
IT STARTS WITH A B.
BULL --
>> YOU DIDN'T BELIEVE IT?
>> I DIDN'T BELIEVE IT BECAUSE
HERE YOU HAD AN ATTACK WITH
ROCKET-PROPELLED HAND GRENADES,
MORTARS, VERY WELL EXECUTED,
VERY WELL PREPARED.
MAYBE I WAS A LITTLE MORE
SENSITIVE TO IT BECAUSE IT WAS
ON THE ANNIVERSARY OF SEPTEMBER
11th, I HAD JUST COME FROM A
DINNER WITH ALL THE PEOPLE THAT
SURVIVED SEPTEMBER 11th WITH ME.
I SAID IS THIS WOMAN OUT OF HER
MIND?
WHAT IS SHE TALKING ABOUT, A
SPONTANEOUS ATTACK?
DID SOMEBODY GIVE HER THAT?
AND THIS IDEA THAT SHE JUST READ
THE NOTES.
DON'T YOU EXERCISE SOME
INTELLIGENCE ABOUT THIS?
>> IN AN OP-ED PIECE IN THE
"WASHINGTON POST" SHE SAYS THESE
UNCLASSIFIED POINTS SHE RECEIVED
WERE CONSISTENT WITH THE
CLASSIFIED ASSESSMENTS I
RECEIVED AS A SENIOR POLICY
MAKER.
I HAVE NEVER SOUGHT IN ANY WAY,
SHAPE OR FORM TO MISLEAD THE
AMERICAN PUBLIC.
TO DO SO WOULD RUN COUNTER TO MY
CHARACTER AND MY LIFE OF PUBLIC
SERVICE.
IN RECENT WEEKS, NEW LINES OF
ATTACK HAVE BEEN RAISED TO
MALIGN MY CHARACTER AND MY
CAREER.
WITH ALL THE GENERAL PETRAEUS
CONFUSION, THERE WAS AN
IMPLICATION THAT PERHAPS SHE HAD
WITHHELD CLASSIFIED INFORMATION
FOR NATIONAL SECURITY REASONS,
WHICH WAS THE BIT THAT HAD
LINKED TO POSSIBLE AL QAEDA
INVOLVEMENT.
SHE'S MAKING IT PRETTY CLEAR,
THOUGH, THAT ALL THE
INTELLIGENCE SHE RECEIVED,
CLASSIFIED OR UNCLASSIFIED, WAS
CONSISTENT.
THEREFORE, WE HAVE TO ASSUME DID
NOT SAY THIS IS LIKELY TO HAVE
BEEN AN AL QAEDA-RELATED ATTACK.
>> AND SHE DEMONSTRATED SHE'S AN
READER OF NOTES AND NOT AN
ANALYZER OF EVENTS.
>> WHAT WAS HER JOB THAT DAY,
RUDY, TO BE FAIR?
>> COMMON SENSE.
THEY GAVE HER A STORY THAT
DIDN'T MEET THE SMELL TEST.
A STRONG PERSON SAYS GARBAGE,
I'M NOT GOING TO REPEAT IT.
I'M SORRY.
I HAVE DONE THAT.
THIS DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE TO
ME.
DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE THAT THIS
WAS A SPONTANEOUS ATTACK.
AND THEN THERE WAS THIS
TREMENDOUS PRESSURE TO TRY TO
SAY THIS WAS A SPONTANEOUS
ATTACK, TRY TO LINK IT TO THAT
MOHAMMED MOVIE THAT PRESIDENT
OBAMA TRIED TO LINK IT TO FOR
THE NEXT TWO WEEKS.
>> DO YOU THINK SHE LIED?
>> I DON'T KNOW THAT.
FOR ME SHE'S UNQUALIFIED TO BE
SECRETARY OF STATE BECAUSE SHE
DOESN'T SEEM TO HAVE THE
INDEPENDENT JUDGMENT TO MAKE
ANALYSIS LIKE THESE TALKING
POINTS DON'T MAKE SENSE.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID AFTER
THE RESIGNATION CAME IN, I
DEEPLY REGRET THE UNFAIR AND
MISLEADING ATTACKS ON SUSAN RICE
IN RECENT WEEKS.
THE OTHER THING I'VE BEEN
HEARING TODAY FROM MANY PEOPLE
IN WASHINGTON IS, LOOK, YES, THE
BENGHAZI THING WAS PROBABLY PART
OF THIS, BUT ACTUALLY WHAT
WORSENED HER CASE REALLY WAS
WHEN SHE WENT TO TRY AND HAVE IT
OUT WITH SENATORS McCAIN AND THE
OTHERS AND REALLY CAME OFF
SECOND BEST AGAIN.
SHE GOT LED DOWN A GARDEN PATH
AND CAME OUT WITH THORNS
EVERYWHERE.
AND PEOPLE WERE SAYING, YOU
KNOW, SHE'S JUST A BIT
INEXPERIENCED TO DEAL WITH
BRUISES LIKE THIS.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN FOR HER ON
THE WORLD STAGE.
IS THAT A FAIR CRITICISM?
>> ALSO FAIR.
WAS SHE IN ABOVE HER HEAD?
QUITE POSSIBLE.
MAYBE SHE WAS IN ABOVE HER HEAD
AND NOT REALLY UNDERSTANDING HOW
TO ANALYZE INTELLIGENCE WELL
ENOUGH.
NOT HAVING ENOUGH INDEPENDENT
KNOWLEDGE TO APPLY TO IT TO
REALIZE THIS IS A MISTAKE.
WHEN I HEARD IT, WHEN JOHN
McCAIN HEARD IT, WE IMMEDIATELY
KNEW IT WAS A STORY THAT JUST
DIDN'T FLY.
MAYBE BECAUSE WE HAVE A LOT MORE
EXPERIENCE THAN SHE DOES.
>> I INTERVIEWED JOHN McCAIN AND
LINDSEY GRAHAM THIS WEEK WHO
BOTH SAID THIS.
WATCH THIS.
>> THE FACT IS SHE NOT ONLY GAVE
WRONG INFORMATION, BUT SHE GAVE
THE PARTY LINE THAT, FOR
EXAMPLE, THAT AL QAEDA IS
DECIMATED.
AL QAEDA IS NOT DECIMATED.
THAT OUR EMBASSIES AND
CONSULATES ARE SECURE.
THEY ARE NOT SECURE.
SO EVERYBODY -- WE ARE ALL
RESPONSIBLE FOR WHAT WE SAY.
SO WE'LL GO THROUGH THE PROCESS,
IF SHE IS NOMINATED, AND WE'LL
SEE.
>> I THINK THE INTELLIGENCE WAS
SANITIZED OR CREATED A FALSE
NARRATIVE.
I'VE SEEN THIS MOVIE WHERE.
>> WOULD YOU OBJECT TO HER
BECOMING SECRETARY OF STATE
PERSONALLY?
>> PERSONALLY I DON'T BELIEVE
SHE WOULD SERVE THE COUNTRY WELL
IN THAT CAPACITY.
>> WE'RE WILLING TO GIVE HER THE
NOMINATION PROCESS, BUT SHE'S
GOT A LOT TO PROVE.
>> I MEAN CRITICS ARE SAYING,
LOOK, SHE'S BASICALLY BEEN
STITCHED UP HERE BY A LOT OF
OLDER GUYS IN THE REPUBLICAN
PARTY WHO HAVE LOOKED AT A
BRIGHT YOUNG WOMAN AND THOUGHT
WE'RE GOING TO GET YOU OUT OF
HERE.
>> A BRIGHT YOUNG WOMAN WOULDN'T
HAVE MADE THAT STATEMENT.
I BRIGHT YOUNG WOMAN WOULD HAVE
HAD ENOUGH INDEPENDENT
KNOWLEDGE, ENOUGH INDEPENDENT
JUDGMENT TO REALIZE SHE WAS
BEING FED A LOAD OF MULARKEY.
IN THE WORDS OF OUR VICE
PRESIDENT.
>> SHE'S CLEARLY BRIGHT, RUDY.
SHE'S NOT A STUPID WOMAN.
SHE'S A VERY INTELLIGENT WOMAN.
>> OBVIOUSLY NOT WITH ENOUGH
INFORMATION, NOT WITH ENOUGH
EXPERIENCE TO KNOW HOW TO
CRITICALLY ANALYZE INTELLIGENCE.
>> IF JOHN KERRY GETS THE JOB --
DO YOU THINK HE SHOULD, FIRST OF
ALL?
WOULD YOU SUPPORT THAT?
>> WOULD TI SUPPORT IT?
IF THE PRESIDENT WANTED JOHN
KERRY, I SEE NO REASON TO STAND
IN THE WAY OF JOHN KERRY AS
SECRETARY OF STATE.
I'M CERTAINLY IF I WERE
PRESIDENT NEVER SELECT JOHN
KERRY AS SECRETARY OF STATE.
>> WHY?
>> I THINK SOME PEOPLE IN OUR
MILITARY WILL HAVE A VERY HARD
TIME.
THOSE PEOPLE WHO WERE IN THE
HANOI HILTON LISTENING TO JOHN
KERRY ATTACKING AMERICA AND
ATTACKING AMERICAN SOLDIERS WILL
HAVE A HARD TIME WITH THIS.
>> IF YOU WERE PRESIDENT OBAMA,
WHO WOULD YOU GO FOR?
>> WHAT I'M SAYING IS I'M NOT
PRESIDENT OBAMA.
ARE YOU SAYING TO ME IS THIS AN
ACCEPTABLE CHOICE WITHIN THE
REALM OF PRESIDENT OBAMA'S RIGHT
TO CHOOSE?
WHICH I BELIEVE IN VERY MUCH.
YES, THIS IS AN ACCEPTABLE
CHOICE.
>> LET'S MOVE TO THE FISCAL
CLIFF, BECAUSE IT'S BECOME A
REAL PAIN IN THE BACK SIDE FOR
EVERYBODY REALLY AND EVERYBODY
IS WAITING FOR WHAT THEY BELIEVE
TO BE AN INEVITABLE DEAL.
IT WOULD SEEM TODAY THAT JOHN
BOEHNER AND PRESIDENT OBAMA MET
AT THE WHITE HOUSE.
THAT'S A GOOD MOVE.
THEY HAVEN'T COME OUT ATTACKING
EACH OTHER, THAT'S ENCOURAGING.
ARE YOU LOOKING AT THIS AS A
PRE-CHRISTMAS DONE DEAL, RUDY?
>> I THINK SO, BECAUSE IT SEEMS
SO OBVIOUS THAT YOU HAVE TO DO
IT.
I DIDN'T LIKE THE COMMENT THAT
THEY HAD A FRANK TALK.
THAT REMINDS ME OF THE COLD WAR.
THAT'S WHEN KRUSCHEV AND KENNEDY
WOULD MEET AND THE NEXT THING
AFTER YOU SAID THEY HAD A FRANK
CONVERSATION, EVERYONE WENT INTO
SHELTERS AND SAID OH, MY GOD,
WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN NEXT?
TO ME A DEAL IS DOABLE, BUT
YOU'VE GOT -- YOU HAVE TO
RECOGNIZE WHAT BOTH SIDES --
OBVIOUSLY THE PRESIDENT NEEDS A
HIKE IN TAXES.
>> AND THAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN,
ISN'T IT?
LET'S BE HONEST, THE REPUBLICANS
HAVE LOST THAT ARGUMENT.
THE ARGUMENT NOW CLEARLY IS
ABOUT HOW FAR ARE THE SPENDING
CUTS GOING TO GO.
>> NOT ONLY HOW FAR, ARE THEY
GOING TO HAPPEN.
REPUBLICANS DON'T BELIEVE HE'LL
DO SPENDING CUTS.
SO HERE'S MY PROPOSAL, SEE WHAT
IT'S WORTH.
REPUBLICANS AGREE, SPLIT THE
DIFFERENCE.
REPUBLICANS AGREE TO JUMP THE
RATE FROM 35 TO 37 AND OTHER
SIMILAR KINDS OF JUMPS.
DEMOCRATS AGREE TO A TRILLION
DOLLARS, TRILLION AND A HALF
DOLLARS IN SPENDING CUTS.
THE SPENDING CUTS AND THE TAX
INCREASES GO INTO EFFECT AT THE
SAME TIME.
BECAUSE HERE'S WHAT REPUBLICANS
ARE REALLY WORRIED ABOUT.
THEY'RE WORRIED ABOUT WE'LL GIVE
THEM THE TAX INCREASES, THEY'LL
SAY, DON'T WORRY, AND THEN A
YEAR FROM NOW THEY'LL BE VERY,
VERY FEW SPENDING DECREASES.
SO IF YOU COULD LINK THE TWO
THINGS TOGETHER AND SAY, OKAY,
WE CAN'T GET ALL THE SPENDING
REDUCTIONS DONE RIGHT NOW.
WE'LL AGREE ON A TAX INCREASE OF
A CERTAIN AMOUNT.
WE'LL AGREE ON SPENDING
DECREASES FOR REAL.
THEY GO INTO EFFECT JUNE 30th.
JUNE 30th BOTH THINGS HAPPEN.
I DON'T SEE REPUBLICANS AGREEING
TO A TAX INCREASE WITHOUT
GETTING THEIR SPENDING CUTS KIND
OF LOCKED IN STONE.
>> I THINK THAT'S PROBABLY VERY
SENSIBLE AND I THINK THE REAL
BATTLE WILL COME WITH THE DEBT
CEILING GETS KICKED INTO THE
ORBIT OF WASHINGTON COME
JANUARY, FEBRUARY.
THAT'S GOING TO BE THE REALLY
TASTY DEBATE, I SUSPECT.
>> WELL, THE PRESIDENT UPPED THE
ANTE BY SAYING HE WANTED SORT OF
PERMANENT AUTHORITY TO RAISE THE
DEBT CEILING AND THAT'S REALLY A
NONSTARTER.
THAT MIGHT EVEN BE
UNCONSTITUTIONAL, I'M NOT SURE.
>> LET'S MOVE TO GUNS BRIEFLY.
THE REASON I WANT TO TALK TO YOU
ABOUT IT, WE HAD ANOTHER OUTRAGE
THIS WEEK, A YOUNG MAN ARMED
WITH AN AR-15 ASSAULT WEAPON
GOES INTO A SHOPPING MALL AND
STARTS SHOOTING PEOPLE.
THANK GOD HIS WEAPON JAMMED AND
HE WASN'T ABLE TO COMMIT THE
ATROCITY WE SAW IN AURORA, BUT
IT WAS THE SAME WEAPON THAT THE
GUY IN AURORA USED, ONE OF THE
FOUR THAT HE HAD WAS AN AR-15.
THEY ARE BANNED IN NEW YORK.
YOU CAN'T GET THEM HERE.
IT'S ILLEGAL.
WELL, THEY'RE NOT BANNED IN MOST
STATES IN AMERICA.
ALMOST EVERYONE I'VE SPOKEN TO,
WHO ISN'T RABIDLY PRO-GUN THINKS
THERE SHOULD BE A SENSIBLE
DEBATE ABOUT BANNING THOSE KINDS
OF WEAPONS AGAIN.
WHAT IS YOUR VIEW?
>> I AGREE THERE SHOULD BE A
SENSIBLE DEBATE ABOUT IT.
I DIDN'T AGREE THAT IT
NECESSARILY SHOULD RESULT IN
IMMEDIATE GUN CONTROL BECAUSE I
LOOK AT THE MURDER THAT TOOK
PLACE IN NORWAY OR IN FINLAND
WHERE, WHAT, 79 PEOPLE WERE
KILLED WITHOUT A GUN.
SO THE REALITY -- THE REALITY IS
IF YOU WANT TO HAVE A SENSIBLE
DEBATE ABOUT WEAPONS LIKE THIS,
WE SHOULD TAKE A LOOK AT HOW CAN
WE PUT SOME RESTRICTIONS ON
THEM, HOW CAN WE MAKE SURE
THEY'RE IN THE HANDS OF THE
RIGHT PEOPLE.
BUT PLEASE DON'T USE IT AS A WAY
OF NOT DEALING WITH WHAT'S
REALLY GOING ON, WHICH THESE
PEOPLE ARE EXTREMELY DANGEROUS.
I THINK A LOT OF ANY INCREASE WE
SEE IN CRIME DOESN'T COME FROM
GUNS, IT COMES FROM A LACK OF
RESPONSIBILITY IN SOCIETY.
>> I KEEP HEARING IT'S NOT THE
GUNS, IT'S ITS PEOPLE.
THAT'S FINE, BUT THIS CHARACTER,
22 YEARS OLD, SEEMED PERFECTLY
NORMAL TO EVERYBODY WHO KNEW
HIM.
FAMILY, FRIENDS, SCHOOL
COLLEAGUES, WHATEVER.
EVERYONE WHO HAD EVER KNOWN THIS
GUY SAID MR. NORMAL.
NOT A CLUE THAT HE WOULD EVER DO
THIS, AND YET HE GOES INTO A
SHOPPING MALL AND BEGINS
SHOOTING PEOPLE IN WHAT WAS A
VERY SIMILAR IN, MY VIEW, KIND
OF THING THAT WE SAW IN AURORA.
MAYBE A COPY CAT, CRY FOR
ATTENTION, WHATEVER IT IS.
YOU CAN'T LEGISLATE FOR THAT.
ALL YOU CAN DO IS TRY TO REMOVE
THAT GUY'S ABILITY TO FIND AN
AR-15.
OR STEAL ONE, AS HE DID.
>> AND YOU'RE NOT GOING TO
REMOVE IT, THOUGH.
>> WHY NOT?
>> IF HE DOESN'T GET THE AR-15,
HE'LL GO GET A HANDGUN.
IF HE DOESN'T DO THAT, HE'LL GO
GET EXPLOSIVES.
IF HE DOESN'T GET THAT, HE'LL GO
GET POISON.
>> BUT DON'T YOU HAVE TO TRY
WHEN YOU'RE RUNNING A COUNTRY
WITH SO MANY GUNS TO TRY TO MAKE
IT HARDER?
>> I THINK I PROBABLY WITH BILL
BRATTEN SEIZED MORE GUNS IN NEW
YORK CITY THAN ANY MAYOR IN
HISTORY.
MAYBE MIKE AND COMMISSIONER
KELLY HAVE MET THAT RECORD, I'M
NOT SURE.
BUT I WAS THE FIRST ONE TO
REALLY SEIZE GUNS.
I BELIEVE IN IT.
I BELIEVE IN GETTING THEM OUT OF
SOCIETY BUT I DON'T BELIEVE IT
ENDS CRIME.
HUMAN BEHAVIOR IS MUCH MORE
IMPORTANT.
IF YOU WANT TO DO A FACTOR, 75%
IS HUMAN BEHAVIOR, 25% IS THE
INSTRUMENT.
WEAPONS LIKE THIS WHERE PEOPLE
CAN KILL, YOU KNOW, MULTIPLE
TIMES VERY, VERY QUICKLY, WE
SHOULD HAVE SOME REASONABLE
RESTRICTIONS ON THE USE OF THEM.
>> THAT IS WHERE I THINK THIS
STRAYS AWAY FROM THE RIGHT TO
BEAR ARMS.
IT SHOULDN'T INCLUDE THOSE KIND
OF WEAPONS WITH THOSE KIND OF
MAGAZINES.
>> ON THE OTHER HAND, IT ALSO
LEADS TO PEOPLE SHOULD BE ABLE
TO ARM THEMSELVES WITH HANDGUNS.
PEOPLE SHOULD BE ABLE TO ARM
THEMSELVES WITH HANDGUNS BECAUSE
IN A SITUATION LIKE THAT, IF
THEY JUST HAPPEN TO HAVE ONE,
AND THIS IDIOT HAS AN AK-47,
THEY CAN KILL HIM.
>> RUDY, ALWAYS GOOD TO TALK TO
YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR COMING
IN.
>> GOOD TO SEE YOU.
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
>> MERRY CHRISTMAS TO YOU TOO.
>>> FIRST, I'M NOT SURPRISED
YOU'RE THE FIRST TO WISH ME A
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
WHEN WE COME BACK I'LL THROW
SOME RED MEAT ON MY ALL STAR
PANEL FROM SUSAN RICE TO THE
COUNTDOWN TO THE FISCAL CLIFF
CRISIS.
STUDY THAT OKED
AT THE LONG TERM HEALTH BENEFITS
OF TAKING MULTIVITAMINS.
HEY USED CENTR SILVER
F T STUDY...
SO I GUESS MY WIFE WAS RIGHT.
Male Anner ] CENTRUM.
WAYS YOUR MOSTOMPLET
SO I GUESS MY WIFE WAS RIGHT.
TRY RUNNING FOUR.NING
A RESTAURANT IS HARD,
FORTUNATELY WE'VE GOT INK.
IT GIVES US 5X THE REWARDS
ON OUR INTERNET, PHONE
CHARGES AND CABLE,
PLUS AT OFFICE SUPPLY STORES.
REWARDS WE PUT RIGHT
BACK INTO OUR BUSINESS.
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
WE'VE EVER WANTED TO DO
AND INK HELPS US DO IT.
MAKE YOUR MARK
WITH INK FROM CHASE.
THOSE LITTLE THINGS
FOR YOU, LIFE'S ABOUT HER.
BUT YOUR ERECTILE DYSFUNCTION -
THAT COULD BE A
QUESTION OF BLOOD FLOW.
CIALIS TADALAFIL
FOR DAILY USE
HELPS YOU
BE READY
ANYTIME THE
MOMENT'S RIGHT.
YOU CAN BE
MORE CONFIDENT
IN YOUR ABILITY TO BE READY.
AND THE SAME CIALIS
IS THE ONLY DAILY
ED TABLET APPROVED TO TREAT
ED AND SYMPTOMS OF BPH,
LIKE NEEDING TO GO
FREQUENTLY OR URGENTLY.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ALL YOUR MEDICAL
CONDITIONS AND MEDICATIONS,
AND ASK IF YOUR HEART IS HEALTHY
ENOUGH FOR SEXUAL ACTIVITY.
DO NOT TAKE CIALIS IF YOU TAKE
NITRATES FOR CHEST PAIN,
AS THIS MAY CAUSE AN UNSAFE
DROP IN BLOOD PRESSURE.
DO NOT DRINK ALCOHOL
IN EXCESS WITH CIALIS.
SIDE EFFECTS MAY INCLUDE
HEADACHE, UPSET STOMACH,
DELAYED BACKACHE OR MUSCLE ACHE.
TO AVOID LONG-TERM INJURY,
SEEK IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
FOR AN ERECTION LASTING
MORE THAN FOUR HOURS.
IF YOU HAVE ANY SUDDEN DECREASE
OR LOSS IN HEARING OR VISION,
OR IF YOU HAVE ANY ALLERGIC
REACTIONS SUCH AS RASH, HIVES,
SWELLING OF THE LIPS,
TONGUE OR THROAT,
OR DIFFICULTY BREATHING
OR SWALLOWING,
STOP TAKING CIALIS AND GET
MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY.
ASK YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT
CIALIS FOR DAILY USE
AND A 30-TABLET FREE TRIAL.
A Hybrid? Most are
just no fun to drive.
Now, here's one that will
make you feel alive.
Meet the five-passenger
Ford C-MAX Hybrid.
C-MAX says ha.
C-MAX says wheeee.
Which is what you get,
don't you see?
Cause C-MAX has lots more
horsepower than Prius v,
a hybrid that C-MAX
also bests in MPG.
Say hi to the all-new 47
combined MPG C-MAX Hybrid.
>>> TODAY I MADE THE DECISION
THAT IT WAS THE BEST THING FOR
OUR COUNTRY, FOR THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE THAT I NOT CONTINUE TO BE
CONSIDERED BY THE PRESIDENT FOR
NOMINATION AS SECRETARY OF STATE
BECAUSE I DIDN'T WANT TO SEE A
CONFIRMATION PROCESS THAT WAS
VERY PROLONGED, VERY
POLITICIZED.
>> AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE TELLING
NBC'S BRIAN WILLIAMS ON ROCK
CENTER WHY SHE WAS WITHDRAWING
HER NAME FOR SECRETARY OF STATE.
LET'S GET TO THE BATTLE IN
AMERICA.
WELCOME TO YOU BOTH.
>> THANKS FOR HAVING US.
>> LET ME START WITH YOU,
MARGARET HOOVER.
THIS WILL BE SEEN AS A BIG WIN
FOR THE OLD GUARD REPUBLICANS.
I INTERVIEWED THE THREE AMIGOS
AS THEY CALL THEMSELVES THIS
WEEK, BUT I'M SURE SENATORS
McCAIN AND GRAHAM WILL SLEEP
EASY TONIGHT KNOWING THEY'VE
SEEN OFF THE CHALLENGE FROM
SUSAN RICE.
ARE THEY RIGHT TO BE PLEASED
ABOUT THIS?
>> I DON'T KNOW FOR THEM IF IT'S
AS MUCH PERSONALLY ABOUT HER OR
IF IT'S ABOUT BENGHAZI.
ALL THREE OF THEM DID
IMMEDIATELY TODAY MAKE
STATEMENTS SAYING WE WILL NOT
STOP THE SCRUTINY ON BENGHAZI
AND WHAT HER WITHDRAWAL DOES IS
STOP THE SCRUTINY OR THE
HEADLINES OF BENGHAZI.
>> THERE'S A FEAR THAT SHE'S
BASICALLY FALLEN ON HER SWORD
BECAUSE THERE'S GOING TO HAVE TO
BE A RESIGNATION LINKED TO
BENGHAZI AT SOME STAGE.
>> IT CERTAINLY WON'T BE HER.
BUT REMEMBER THE FOUNDATION
REALLY STARTED TO CRUMBLE ON
THIS WHEN THE LEFT STOPPED
SUPPORTING SUSAN RICE.
SO AS MUCH AS THE THREE AMIGOS
WERE OUT IN FRONT, MAUREEN DOWD
HAD CRITICAL, CRITICAL REVIEWS
OF HER, EZRA KLEIN, THE
ENVIRONMENTALIST MOVEMENT
STARTED HAVING PROBLEMS WITH
HER.
>> THAT IS TRUE AND I DETECTED
THAT.
THERE WAS ALSO A SENSE WHEN SHE
WENT UP THERE TO SEE THE THREE
AMIGOS AND OTHERS, SHE REALLY
EMERGED LOOKING QUITE WEAKENED
AS IF SHE GOT INTO AN OBVIOUS
TRAP AND BEEN LASSOED ALL OVER
AGAIN.
IT JUST DIDN'T LOOK VERY SMART
POLITICS BY HER.
>> WELL, NO, I THINK SHE TOOK
ONE FOR THE TEAM.
THE PROBLEM IS THAT THE ENTIRE
SITUATION HAS BECOME HIGHLY
POLITICIZED.
FRANKLY GIULIANI SAYING SHE MAY
NOT HAVE BEEN SHARP ENOUGH IS
WHOLLY UNFAIR AND I THINK IT
REALLY IS A TRAGEDY, BECAUSE SHE
REALLY, I WOULD SAY, IS THE BEST
WOMAN FOR THE JOB.
SHE WAS A TRUSTED ADVISER TO THE
PRESIDENT AND SHE HAS DONE MORE
IN TERMS OF PUTTING SANCTIONS
AGAINST IRAN, NORTH KOREA IN HER
CAPACITY AS AMBASSADOR.
IS TRULY A WOMAN WHO UNDERSTANDS
21st CENTURY DIPLOMACY AND
NATIONAL SECURITY.
AND WHAT SHE DID WAS GO AND READ
TALKING POINTS GIVEN TO HER BY
THE NATIONAL SECURITY STAFF AND
DID HER JOB.
HAD SHE GONE IN AND ASSERTED HER
OWN OPINIONS, HER OWN -- IT
WOULD HAVE BEEN SEEN AS PLAYING
POLITICS, WHICH WOULD HAVE BEEN
OUT OF PLACE.
>> OKAY.
BUT MARGARET, WHETHER SHE'S THE
BEST PERSON FOR THE JOB I THINK
IS A FAIRLY ARGUABLE POINT.
I DON'T THINK SHE'S BEEN
MASSIVELY IMPRESSIVE IN THE LAST
FEW MONTHS.
SHE MISLED THE PUBLIC
DELIBERATELY BUT NOT MASSIVELY
IMPRESSIVE.
JOHN KERRY, I WOULD SAY, IS
PROBABLY A BETTER CANDIDATE,
JUST FROM MY DISPASSIONATE EYE.
>> HE PROBABLY WOULDN'T HAVE
MADE THE SAME MISTAKE SHE MADE.
I THINK SENATOR CLINTON PROBABLY
SAID IT BEST WHEN SHE ACTUALLY
MADE EVERY INDICATION THAT SHE
FAVORS JOHN KERRY FOR THE
POSITION, NOT SECRETARY RICE.
HE IS WIDELY RESPECTED IN
WASHINGTON, WHETHER YOU LIKE
HIS -- HE'S BEEN HEAD OF THE
FOREIGN AFFAIRS COMMITTEE FOR
YEARS AND YEARS AND YEARS SO HE
PROBABLY DOES HAVE MORE
EXPERIENCE.
NOT TO KNOCK SUSAN RICE'S
EXPERIENCE CERTAINLY.
I CAN'T IMAGINE THAT SENATOR
McCAIN WILL BE THRILLED WITH THE
FOREIGN POLICY THAT JOHN KERRY
RUNS ANY BETTER THAN SUSAN RICE.
IT WAS THE HANDLING OF THIS AND
THE HANDLING OF THE
ADMINISTRATION WITH BENGHAZI
THAT THIS BECAME THE SYMBOL OF.
>> LET'S MOVE TO THIS RATHER
DIFFICULT SITUATION THE
PRESIDENT FINDS HIMSELF IN WITH
THE TOP FOUR CABINET POSITIONS
COULD ALL BE FILLED BY MEN IT
NOW SEEMS, NO WOMEN AT ALL.
THAT'S NOT GREAT FOR A
PROGRESSIVE PRESIDENT LIKE
BARACK OBAMA, IS IT?
>> YEAH, NO.
I DON'T HAVE A LOT OF GOOD
THINGS TO SAY ABOUT THAT
PROSPECT.
I THINK THE THING IS THERE IS I
DEEP ENOUGH BENCH OF FABULOUS
WOMEN THAT COULD FULFILL THESE
ROLES AND WE SURE WOULD LIKE TO
SEE THEM HOLD THOSE POSITIONS.
SUSAN RICE, I THINK IS NOT JUST
THE BEST WOMAN FOR THE JOB, I
THOUGHT SHE WAS THE BEST PERSON
FOR THE JOB.
IN TERMS OF JOHN KERRY BEING A
SAFE CHOICE, HE'S VANILLA AND
VANILLA IS ALWAYS A SAFE FLAVOR,
RIGHT?
BUT I WOULD SAY ABSOLUTELY IT'S
SOMETHING TO THINK ABOUT IN
TERMS OF I THINK IT'S GOOD TO
HAVE THE RIGHT PERSON FOR THE
JOB ALWAYS.
BUT I THINK IT'S WORTH CHECKING
OUT THE PROSPECTS FOR SURE.
>>> LET'S TURN TO THE FISCAL
CLIFF, THE FRANK MEETING BETWEEN
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND JOHN
BOEHNER.
I BELIEVE THEY JUST CALLED EACH
OTHER NAMES FOR 50 MINUTES AND
WALKED OUT WITH NO DEAL BEING
DONE.
BUT LOOK AT THE FOOTAGE FROM THE
UKRAINE PARLIAMENT.
JUST WHEN YOU THINK WASHINGTON
IS THE WORST IN THE WORLD AT
DOING THINGS TOGETHER, LOOK AT
THESE CLOWNS, THIS IS QUITE
AMAZING.
THIS IS THE UKRAINE PARLIAMENT
ERUPTING INTO OPEN PHYSICAL
WARFARE.
NOW, THERE IS A VOORIEW THAT A D
OLD PUNCH-UP DOES TEND TO
RESOLVE THESE THINGS.
MAYBE JOHN BOEHNER AND BARACK
OBAMA SHOULD JUST SQUARE OFF,
GET IN A RING AND SLUG EACH
OTHER OUT.
>> THIS ISN'T THE FIRST TIME
THIS THING HAPPENED.
THIS HAPPENS ALL THE TIME IN THE
UKRAINE.
>> OR THE BRITISH PAURLIAMENTPA.
IT'S FAR MORE INTERESTING AND
FAR MORE FUN WHEN YOU CAN THROW
A LITTLE HUMOR AND PUNCHES.
MAYBE THEY NEED TO GET IT OUT OF
THEIR SYSTEMS.
>> BUT BRITISH YOU HAVE
RHETORICAL PUNCHES.
>> ON A VAGUELY SERIOUS POINT
THOUGH, MARGARET HOOVER, LET ME
ASK MARGARET FIRST AND THEN YOU
MARJORIE, ARE WE GOING TO GET A
DEAL DONE BEFORE CHRISTMAS?
ALL THE HINTS I'M GETTING IS
YES, IT'S GOING TO BE A DEAL.
>> I THINK WE'RE GOING TO GET A
DEAL AND I THINK THE QUESTION IS
HOW HEAVILY SCORNED IS JOHN
BOEHNER AND HOW MUCH DOES THAT
HURT BARACK OBAMA'S MOMENTUM
GOING INTO THE FIRST PART OF THE
NEXT DEAL BECAUSE HE WANTS TO
GET IMMIGRATION DONE IN JANUARY
AND FEBRUARY.
IF HE'S GOT AN IMPENDING DEBT
CEILING DEBATE HE'S GOING TO
HAVE TO DEAL WITH INSTEAD THAT,
WILL PUT REAL MOMENTUM INTO IT.
SO WHAT IS HE GOING TO GIVE
BOEHNER --
>> IF OBAMA WINS THE VICTORY
OVER RAISING INCOME TAX FOR THE
WEALTHY 2%, HE WILL SEE THAT AS
A MAJOR TRIUMPH.
IT WAS AN ELECTION PLEDGE.
HE WILL THINK, OKAY, ONE FOR THE
NEW GIPPER.
BUT HE'S GOT TO GIVE JOHN
BOEHNER SOMETHING ELSE.
HE'S GOT TO GIVE HIM SOMETHING
HE CAN TAKE BACK TO HIS FAITHFUL
AND SAY I'VE GOT SOMETHING TOO.
>> I'M GOING TO START USING
GIPPER TOO.
YES, I THINK HE WILL GET HIS BIT
THERE, BUT I THINK HE WILL HAVE
TO GIVE, ABSOLUTELY.
IT'S GOING TO BE A COMPROMISE IN
THE END.
HONESTLY, THIS IS CLASSIC
NEGOTIATION 101.
THEY'RE GOING TO WAIT UNTIL THE
LAST MINUTE SO THEY CAN BOTH SAY
TO THEIR SIDE, HEY, LOOK, WE
FOUGHT THIS TOOTH AND NAIL ALL
THE WAY UP TO THE END AND THEN
WE GOT OUR PIECE.
SO IT'S NOT SURPRISING.
YOU LOOK AT ANY OF THE PAST
LEGISLATIVE ISSUES, IT ALWAYS
PUSHES TO THE LAST MINUTE
BECAUSE THAT'S HOW IT'S DONE.
THAT'S HOW YOU KEEP EVERYBODY
HAPPY.
>> AND IT DOES SEEM UNBELIEVABLY
CHILDISH.
BUT THERE YOU ARE.
>> AND HOPEFULLY SOME PUNCHES
AND A DANCE AT THE END.
>> THE UKRAINE-STYLE PUNCHOUT.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> THE BRITISH WAY.
MARGARET HOOVER, MARJORIE, THANK
YOU VERY MUCH INDEED.
>>> WARREN BUFFETT'S SON,
HOWARD, JOINS US TO TALK ABOUT
MONEY, POLITICS, TAXES, HIS
FAMOUS DAD AND MORE.
IT SHOULD BE A FASCINATING FEW
MINUTES WITH A GREAT MAN.
[ sniffs ] I HAVE A COLD.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
AND HIS NEW BOSS TOLD HIM
TWO THINGS --
COOK WHAT YOU LOVE,
AND SAVE YOUR MONEY.
JOE DOESN'T KNOW IT YET,
BUT HE'LL WORK HIS WAY UP
FROM BUSSER TO WAITER TO CHEF
BEFORE OPENING A RESTAURANT
SPECIALIZING IN FISH AND GAME
FROM THE GREAT NORTHWEST.
HE'LL START INVESTING EARLY,
HE'LL FIND SOME GOOD PEOPLE
TO HELP GUIDE HIM,
AND HE'LL SET MONEY ASIDE
FROM HIS FIRST DAY OF WORK
TO HIS LAST,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
TIME FOR CITI PRICE REWIND.
BECAUSE YOUR DAUGHTER REALLY
WANTS THAT PINK CASTLE THING.
AND YOU REALLY DON'T WANT
TO PAY MORE THAN YOU HAVE TO.
ONLY CITI PRICE REWIND
AUTOMATICALLY SEARCHES
FOR THE LOWEST PRICE.
AND IF IT FINDS ONE, YOU GET
REFUNDED THE DIFFERENCE.
JUST USE YOUR CITI CARD
AND REGISTER YOUR PURCHASE
ONLINE.
HAVE A SUPER SPARKLY DAY!
OK.
[ Male Announcer ] NOW ALL
YOU NEED IS A MAGIC CARRIAGE.
CITI PRICE REWIND.
START SAVING
AT CITI.COM/PRICEREWIND.
LOOK THIS ISN'T
MY FIRST CHRISTMAS.
THESE DEALS ALL SEEM GREAT
AT THE TIME...
BUT LATER...
[ shirt ]
MERRY CHRISTMAS, EVERYBODY!
NOT SO MUCH.
HO HO HO!
THIS ISN'T
THAT KIND OF DEAL.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SAVE ON GROUND SHIPPING
AT FEDEX OFFICE.
>>> I DON'T BELIEVE IN LOTS OF
INHERITED WEALTH.
I HAVEN'T BEEN SPENDING MY LIFE
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT HOW TO
TRANSFER WEALTH AND NOT HAVE
TAXES AND ALL OF THAT SO THERE
CAN BE A DYNASTY OF ALL KINDS OF
LITTLE BUFFETS GOING AROUND FOR
HUNDREDS OF YEARS NEVER HAVING
TO DO ANYTHING.
>> THE RICHEST MAN IN AMERICA,
WARREN BUFFETT.
WITH ME IS ONE OF THE KIDS,
HOWARD G. BUFFET, PRESIDENT OF
THE HOWARD G. BUFFET FOUNDATION.
WELCOME TO YOU, SIR.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> YOU ARE THE MIDDLE CHILD OF
WARREN BUFFETT.
WHAT'S IT LIKE, I SPENT -- I
TOLD YOU IN THE BREAK I SPENT A
GREAT HOLIDAY ONCE READING THAT
BIOGRAPHY ABOUT YOUR FATHER AND
GOT TO KNOW ALL OF YOU
VICARIOUSLY THROUGH THIS BOOK.
IT WAS ABSOLUTELY RIVETING AND
COMPELLING.
WHAT'S IT LIKE TO BE WARREN
BUFFETT'S SON?
>> WELL, FIRST, I'M AFRAID YOU
KNOW MORE ABOUT ME THAN I KNOW,
SO THAT'S MY FIRST CONCERN.
YOU KNOW, I DON'T THINK OF IT AS
BEING WARREN BUFFETT'S SON.
YOU KNOW, WE GREW UP, AS MANY
PEOPLE KNOW AND SOME PEOPLE
DON'T BELIEVE, IN A VERY MODEST
ENVIRONMENT.
AND I NEVER -- WE NEVER REALLY
WERE EVEN AWARE THAT MY DAD WAS
REALLY MAKING MONEY UNTIL
PROBABLY TOWARDS THE END OF
JUNIOR HIGH AND THEN INTO HIGH
SCHOOL.
AND THEN YOU'RE A LITTLE OLDER
AND YOU JUST TAKE IT AS IT
COMES.
BUT I'VE NEVER THOUGHT OF IT
THAT WAY.
>> WHAT I LOVE ARE THE LITTLE
TINY BITS OF TRIVIAL DETAIL
ABOUT YOUR RELATIONSHIP WITH HIM
WHEN YOU WERE YOUNGER.
THERE'S A GREAT STORY THAT YOU
TELL ABOUT YOU ASKED YOUR FATHER
IF YOU COULD HAVE A CAR.
AND IN EXCHANGE HE SAID, RIGHT,
YOU CAN.
BUT YOU CAN'T HAVE ANY BIRTHDAY
OR CHRISTMAS PRESENTS FOR SOME
INDETERMINANT PERIOD.
HOW LONG WAS THE PERIOD?
>> THREE YEARS.
AND I KNEW HE WAS GOING TO GIVE
ME $5,000 AND I THOUGHT I COULD
GET THE CAR FOR $5,000 AND I WAS
$2500 SHORT.
THAT WAS A LOT OF MONEY.
>> HOW DID YOU FEEL?
DIDDY EVER NEARLY SUCCUMB TO THE
PRESSURE?
>> OH, NO, IT WAS A DEAL.
IN OUR HOUSEHOLD A DEAL IS A
DEAL.
>> WAS THERE A HANDSHAKE OR
FORMAL CONTRACT?
>> NO, THE HANDSHAKE WAS IT.
>> HAS YOUR DAD ALWAYS BEEN A
HANDSHAKE MAN?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
HE'S MADE SOME OF THE BIGGEST
DEALS ANY BUSINESSMAN HAS EVER
MADE ON A HANDSHAKE.
>> AND YOU THE SAME?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
I MEAN IF YOU DON'T TRUST WHO
YOU'RE DOING A DEAL WITH, THEN
YOU SHOULDN'T BE DOING A DEAL.
A CONTRACT DOESN'T MAKE A BAD
GUY DO A GOOD DEAL.
SO YOU'VE GOT TO DO IT ON A
HANDSHAKE.
>> THE OTHER STORY I ABSOLUTELY
LOVED WAS AS A KID YOU TURNED
YOUR BACK YARD INTO A FARM AND
THAT'S BECOME YOUR GREAT PASSION
OR LOVE.
YOUR FATHER LATER BOUGHT LAND
FOR YOU AND CHARGED YOU RENT,
BUT THIS WAS THE TWIST.
HE TIED IT TO THE AMOUNT OF YOUR
BODY WEIGHT.
THE HIGHER YOUR WEIGHT, THE
HIGHER THE RENT.
DID IT WORK?
THIS COULD BE THE GREATEST DIET
THING IN HISTORY.
>> IT DIDN'T WORK.
AND HE WOULD TELL YOU IT DIDN'T
WORK.
YOU KNOW, SO WE MOVED ON TO THE
NEXT THING.
>> WHAT DID WORK OVER THE YEARS?
>> WELL, I THINK THE THINGS THAT
HAVE WORKED, I'M NOT SURE
EXACTLY SPECIFICALLY WHAT YOU'RE
AFTER.
>> WELL, HE MUST HAVE IMPARTED
SO MUCH WISDOM TO YOU OVER THE
YEARS.
>> HE HAS BEEN AN AMAZING
MENTOR.
I USED TO SIT -- I'M NOT SURE HE
EVEN KNOWS I DID THIS.
BUT I USED TO SIT IN A CHAIR OR
ON THE COUCH OR SOMETHING IN THE
SAME ROOM.
HE'S BE ON THE PHONE NEGOTIATING
SOMETHING AND I'D JUST LISTEN TO
HIM.
I'D ONLY HEAR ONE SIDE OF THE
CONVERSATION, BUT THAT WAS
ENOUGH TO GET A GOOD IDEA OF
WHAT HE WAS DOING OF THE AND I
MEAN IT WAS AN AMAZING
EXPERIENCE.
>> YOU HAVE THIS FOUNDATION
INVOLVED VERY MUCH WITH HUNGER
AND CHARITY WORK, YOU VISITED
THE CONGO WITH BEN AFFLECK.
OBVIOUSLY A PASSION OF YOURS.
>> WELL, I JUST GOT BACK FROM
EASTERN CONGO ABOUT FOUR DAYS
AGO, THE SECOND TRIP IN FIVE
WEEKS.
CONGO IS AN AREA WHERE A LOT OF
PEOPLE ARE GETTING THE DEBATE
WRONG.
I WILL TELL YOU, YOU'VE BEEN
TALKING ALL ABOUT SUSAN RICE AND
I DON'T KNOW THE POLITICS OF
SUSAN RICE.
SHE MADE A STATEMENT WHICH IS
DEAD RIGHT, WHICH IS IF IT ISN'T
THEM IN 23, IT WILL BE THEM.
SINCE 1990 IT HAS NOT MOVED AND
STILL HAS REMAINED AT THE BOTTOM
OF THE U.N. INDEX FOR POVERTY
AND HUMAN SUFFERING.
SO -- AND IT RANKS ALMOST DEAD
LAST AND MO ABRAMS INDEX NEXT TO
SOMALIA.
I WAS IN SOMALIA ABOUT FIVE
WEEKS AGO.
I TELL YOU, I CAN UNDERSTAND
THAT.
SO IT'S A TOUGH PLACE, IT'S A
TOUGH -- IT'S FULL OF ATROCITIES
AND HUMAN RIGHTS VIOLATIONS.
AND SOMEHOW WE HAVE TO SUPPORT
THE GOVERNMENT OF DRC TO DO A
BETTER JOB AND TO TAKE EASTERN
CONGO AND TURN IT -- IT HAS
INCREDIBLE MINERAL -- SOME OF
THE ESTIMATES ARE $24 TRILLION
OF WEALTH TO BRING OUT IN THE
FUTURE.
IT COULD BE A VERY RICH COUNTRY.
>> LET'S TALK BRIEFLY THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
YOUR FATHER HAS BEEN VERY VOCAL
ABOUT TAXES.
HE SAYS COME ON, BRING IT TO ME,
TAX ME MORE.
OBVIOUSLY YOU'LL BE IN THE
FIRING LINE BECAUSE YOU'RE NOT A
POOR MAN, ARE YOU.
ARE YOU HAPPY YOUR FATHER IS
LEADING THIS CALL FOR YOU TO
GET --
>> NO, BECAUSE I HEAR FROM ALL
MY REPUBLICAN FRIENDS WHO DON'T
LIKE IT.
YOU KNOW, THE FISCAL CLIFF, YOU
TALK ABOUT IT, IT'S LIKE -- YOU
KNOW, IT'S THE RESULT OF POOR
BEHAVIOR.
NO ONE SHOULD BE SURPRISED.
YOU KNOW, ON THE OTHER HAND THE
WORLD DOESN'T END TOMORROW IF WE
GO OFF THE CLIFF.
COKE SELLS COCA-COLA, BURLINGTON
NORTHERN HAULS FREIGHT.
I WILL TELL YOU, I THINK OF THE
FISCAL CLIFF A LITTLE
DIFFERENTLY.
I PUT IT -- I THINK IT'S
RELATIVE TO THE WORLD.
EVERYBODY IN THE EASTERN CONGO
GETS UP AND THEY'RE FALLING OFF
THE FISCAL CLIFF EVERY MORNING
WHEN THEY GET OUT OF BED TRYING
TO FIGURE OUT IF THEY CAN FEED
THEIR CHILD LIVING ON $1 A DAY
OR HALF A DOLLAR A DAY.
SO I THINK IT'S ALL RELATIVE.
AND THE WORLD DOESN'T END.
AND I'M NOT EVEN SURE THAT GOING
OFF THE CLIFF ISN'T THE SLAP IN
THE FACE WE NEED TO SAY, FOLKS,
WE NEED TO DO BETTER.
>> WOULD YOU BE HAPPY TO PAY
MORE TAX?
>> I DON'T THINK YOU HAVE TO PAY
MORE TAX.
I TELL YOU WHAT I THINK IT
AMOUNTS TO.
WHEN MY DAD STARTED TALKING
ABOUT THIS I STARTED PAYING
ATTENTION TO WHAT TAX I PAID.
I'M IN THE 35% TAX BRACKET.
BUT I WENT BACK AND FIGURED IT
OUT -- I SHOULD SAY MY WIFE WENT
BACK AND FIGURED IT OUT, SHE DID
ALL THE WORK.
YOU KNOW WHAT, WE PAID JUST
UNDER 24% ON AN AVERAGE ACROSS
THE FIVE YEARS.
I THINK IF PEOPLE PAID WHAT THEY
ARE SUPPOSED TO PAY WITHIN THE
TAX BRACKET, YOU DON'T HAVE TO
RAISE TAXES.
>> FINAL QUESTION, WHAT ON EARTH
DO YOU BUY WARREN BUFFETT FOR
CHRISTMAS?
>> NOW YOU'VE PUT ME ON THE
SPOT.
YOU KNOW, I THINK --
>> DO YOU GO BIG, DO YOU GO
SMALL?
>> YOU GO WITH ANY IDEA YOU
HAVE.
>> WHAT DID YOU GET HIM LAST
YEAR?
>> OH, MY GOSH, I'M TRYING TO
REMEMBER WHAT I GOT HIM LAST
YEAR.
I TELL YOU WHAT I GIVE HIM FOR
CHRISTMAS, YOU'LL LIKE THIS.
WHAT I GIVE HIM FOR CHRISTMAS IS
I WAIT AND I HAND HIM MY RENT
CHECK FOR THE FARM AT CHRISTMAS
TIME.
THAT'S WHAT I DO EVERY YEAR.
HE LOVES IT, HE TAKES IT.
>> GOOD TO SEE YOU.
I'M GOING TO GET YOU BACK ONE
DAY WITH YOUR FATHER AND MAYBE
YOUR SON AS WELL, THREE
GENERATIONS.
>> I WOULD LOVE THAT.
>> THANKS VERY MUCH.
>> YOU BET.
>>> LIFE ON DEATH ROW AND
AFTERWARDS.
MY EMOTIONAL INTERVIEW WITH THE
WEST MEMPHIS THREE'S DAMIEN
EKLES.
>> THE MEDIA PORTRAYS THIS IMAGE
TO SOCIETY THAT DEATH ROW IS
FULL OF CRIMINAL GENIUS HANNIBAL
LECTER TYPES AND IT'S NOT THE
CASE.
Oh...there you go.
Wooohooo....Hahaahahaha!
I'm gonna stand
up to her!
No you're not.
I know.
You know Ronny folks who save
hundreds of dollars
switching to GEICO
sure are happy.
How happy are they Jimmy?
Happier than a witch in
a broom factory.
Get happy. Get GEICO.
Fifteen minutes could save you
fifteen percent or more.
HOW THEY'LL LIVE TOMORROW.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
WELCOME TO CHEVY'S
YEAR-END EVENT.
SO, THE 5.3-LITER V8 SILVERADO
CAN TOW UP TO 9,600 POUNDS?
315 HORSEPOWER.
WHAT'S THAT IN
REINDEER-POWER?
[ laughs ]
[ pencil scratches ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHEVY'S GIVING MORE.
GET THE BEST OFFER
OF THE YEAR --
0% APR FINANCING FOR 60 MONTHS
PLUS $1,000 HOLIDAY BONUS CASH.
PLUS TRADE UP FOR AN ADDITIONAL
$1,000 TRADE-IN ALLOWANCE.
HURRY.
BONUS CASH ENDS JANUARY 2ND.
ADT CAN HELP YOU
TURN ON A FEW LIGHTS.
ACCESS CAMERAS FROM ANYWHERE
TO HELP YOU KEEP AN EYE
ON THINGS.
EVEN BRING FAMILY IN
FROM THE COLD
WHEN YOU'RE NOT THERE.
NOW GET THE ADVANCED TECHNOLOGY
OF ADT
STARTING AT JUST $99
AND SAVE $300.
WITH ADT, YOU GET 24/7
FAST RESPONSE MONITORING
THAT HELPS PROTECT YOU
FROM BURGLARY, FIRE,
AND HIGH LEVELS
OF CARBON MONOXIDE.
PLUS REMOTE ACCESS
TO YOUR HOME.
EVEN CONTROL YOUR THERMOSTAT
TO HELP SAVE ENERGY AND MONEY.
GET ADT INSTALLED
STARTING AT JUST $99.
THAT'S A $300 SAVINGS.
YOU MAY EVEN SAVE UP TO 20%
ON YOUR HOMEOWNERS INSURANCE.
FOR EVERYTHING
THAT MATTERS MOST.
ADT. ALWAYS THERE.
>>> STILL VERY MUCH IN SHOCK,
STILL OVERWHELMED.
YOU KNOW, YOU KIND OF HAVE TO
TAKE INTO CONSIDERATION THAT I
SPENT ALMOST THE PAST DECADE IN
ABSOLUTE SOLITARY CONFINEMENT,
SO I'M NOT USED TO BEING AROUND
ANYONE, MUCH LESS THIS MANY
PEOPLE.
IT'S KIND OF OVERWHELMING.
>> DAMIEN ECHOLS FREE, ONE OF
THE WEST MEMPHIS THREE CONVICTED
OF THE 1993 MURDERS OF THREE
BOYS.
THEY HAVE ALWAYS MAINTAINED
THEIR INNOCENCE.
SPENT NEARLY TWO DECADES IN
PRISON BEFORE THEY WERE RELEASED
LAST YEAR.
IT'S THE SUBJECT OF A
DOCUMENTARY PRODUCED BY ECHOLS
AND HIS WIFE, LORI DAVIS.
THEY JOIN ME ALONG WITH THE
FILM'S DIRECTOR, LORI BERG.
FIRST OF ALL, YOU LOOK A LOT
BETTER THAN THE LAST TIME I
INTERVIEWED YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> SO YOUR REINTEGRATION BACK
INTO NORMAL LIFE CLEARLY GOING
REASONABLY WELL.
>> YES.
>> HOW DIFFICULT HAS IT BEEN FOR
YOU, DAMIEN?
>> IT WAS INCREDIBLY DIFFICULT.
YOU KNOW, I REALLY DIDN'T EVEN
HAVE AN IDEA HOW DIFFICULT IT
WAS GOING TO BE.
FOR THE FIRST AT LEAST THREE
MONTHS THAT I WAS OUT, I WAS IN
A STATE OF EXTREME SHOCK AND
TRAUMA.
I COULDN'T DO ANYTHING BY MYSELF
OR FOR MYSELF.
I NEEDED SOMEONE WITH ME
CONSTANTLY.
I JUST -- IT WAS LIKE A COMPLETE
AND ABSOLUTE SHOCK TO THE
SYSTEM.
>> WHAT ARE THE PHYSICAL SIDE
EFFECTS THAT YOU STILL -- YOU'RE
WEARING DARK GLASSES.
CLEARLY YOU STILL HAVE
SENSITIVITY FOR YOUR EYES, NOT
HAVING NATURAL SUNLIGHT FOR
YEARS.
>> YEAH.
>> WHAT ELSE?
>> I'VE GAINED 60 POUNDS BECAUSE
I HAVE ADEQUATE NUTRITION AND
DECENT EXERCISE, THINGS LIKE
THAT.
I STILL HAVE A LOT OF KIDNEY
ISSUES BECAUSE I WAS BEATEN
PRETTY BAD AT ONE POINT.
I ALSO HAVE A LOT OF DENTAL
ISSUES, WHICH THANKFULLY I'VE
BEEN ABLE TO GET FIXED OVER THE
PAST YEAR, A LOT OF NERVE
DAMAGE, THINGS LIKE THAT.
>> LORI, WHAT'S IT BEEN LIKE TO
HAVE HIM IN NORMAL LIFE AND HOW
DO YOU THINK HE'S BEEN COPING?
>> FIRST OF ALL, IT'S AMAZING TO
HAVE HIM OUT HERE WITH US.
BUT IT'S TRUE, NO ONE COULD
FORESEE HOW HE WAS GOING TO
COPE.
AND SO IT WAS DIFFICULT.
AND I DIDN'T UNDERSTAND HOW HE
WAS FEELING AND THE ANXIETY AND
ALL OF THAT THAT HE WAS DEALING
WITH FOR AT LEAST SIX MONTHS.
AFTER THAT, IT'S JUST BEEN A
PROCESS.
BUT IT'S -- THERE'S NO
PRECEDENT.
YOU KNOW, THERE'S NO PLACE,
THERE'S NO GUIDE BOOK OR
ANYTHING TO KNOW WHAT TO DO.
>> WHAT DO YOU THINK HAVE BEEN
THE HARDEST THINGS FOR DAMIEN TO
DEAL WITH?
>> IT'S THE LITTLE THINGS, LIKE
GOING TO THE BANK AND FILLING
OUT A DEPOSIT SLIP OR GOING
THROUGH SECURITY AT THE AIRPORT.
IT'S THE ANXIETY THAT I DIDN'T
UNDERSTAND IS JUST HUGE FOR HIM.
JUST THE DAY-TO-DAY LIFE.
>> IT'S QUITE AN EXTRAORDINARY
STORY.
I WAS GRIPPED BY IT WHEN I DID
THE PREVIOUS INTERVIEW.
THIS SHOCKING MISCARRIAGE OF
JUSTICE FOR THESE MEN.
WHAT WAS IT THAT APPEALED TO YOU
FROM A DOCUMENTARY MAKER
POINTING OF VIEW?
>> WELL, THE STORY HAD SO MANY
TWISTS AND TURNS BUT AT THE END
OF THE DAY THERE WAS A MAN ON
DEATH ROW AND TWO SERVING LIFE
SENTENCES FOR SOMETHING THEY
DIDN'T DO.
I THINK THE MOST GRIPPING THING
WAS THAT THEY WERE CONVICTED AS
IF THEY PERPETRATED THESE
SATANIC MURDERS.
ONCE WE DISCOVERED THAT SNAPPING
TURTLES ACTUALLY CAUSED THE
WOUNDS THAT WERE BEING JUDGED AS
KNIFE WOUNDS, THIS WAS A WHOLE
DIFFERENT MURDER CASE.
>> LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT A CLIP
FROM THE MOVIE BECAUSE IT
PERTAINS EXACTLY TO WHAT YOU
JUST MENTIONED.
>> IF YOU ASK ME, THE SING IT
GREATEST OFFENSE COMMITTED IN
THIS CASE IS WHAT WAS DONE BY
JOHN WITH THE KNIFE AND THE LEG.
>> GOING DIVERS SEARCHED A SMAL
AND THAT SEARCH PRODUCED A
KNIFE.
>> TO GO OUT THERE IN THIS BIG
POND AND TO GO RIGHT THERE AND
JUST LESS THAN 30 MINUTES AND
COME UP WITH THIS KNIFE, I MEAN,
YOU WIN THE LOTTERY.
>> WIN THE LOTTERY.
OF COURSE THE LOTTERY TURNED OUT
TO BE A SHAMEFUL FARCE, DIDN'T
IT?
>> AND WHAT YOU DIDN'T HEAR WAS
ACTUALLY THAT THAT KNIFE WAS
ACTUALLY THROWN IN THE LAKE A
YEAR BEFORE THE MURDERS EVEN
HAPPENED AND IT ACTUALLY WAS
USED IN THE TRIAL TO CONVICT
THESE GUYS.
SO IT WAS JUST SUCH A TRAGEDY IN
THE MAKING.
>> AND IN RELATION TO THE WOUNDS
TO THESE POOR BOYS, AND WE'LL
COME TO THE FACT THERE'S NEVER
BEEN ANYONE REALLY WHO ACTUALLY
DID THIS BROUGHT TO JUSTICE, THE
INTERESTING THING ABOUT THIS
DOCUMENTARY UNRAVELS IS THAT
THESE WOUNDS WERE MUCH MORE
LIKELY TO HAVE BEEN CAUSED BY
TURTLES THAN BY A KNIFE.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
THERE WAS NO DEPTH TO THE
WOUNDS, THEY WERE SCRATCH MARKS.
BUT PEOPLE WERE PRESENTED WITH
THE INFORMATION AS IF THEY WERE
STABBED TO DEATH.
AND THERE WAS NO DEPTH.
THERE WAS NO ORGAN DAMAGE OR
ANYTHING.
>> THE DOCUMENTARY IS VERY
POWERFUL.
IT TALKS OF BEING THE FIRST
CROWD SOURCED INVESTIGATION
EVER, AND YOU WORKED WITH
INVESTIGATORS AND FORENSIC TEAMS
TO REVEAL FALSE CONFESSIONS,
JUNK SCIENCE AND THE PROSECUT
PROSECUTORIAL MISCONDUCT.
>> WELL, BECAUSE THIS WAS A
CLOSED CASE AND THEY WERE
CONVICTED, EVERYTHING BECAME
AVAILABLE ON THE PUBLIC RECORD
AND PEOPLE WERE FASCINATED WITH
THIS STORY FOR ALL DIFFERENT
REASONS AND STARTED GOING DOWN
TO THE WEST MEMPHIS POLICE
DEPARTMENT AND TAKING PICTURES
OF EVIDENCE AND THEN THE
INTERNET BEGAN TO GET -- TO
BECOME WHAT IT IS TODAY.
AND SO PEOPLE WERE LIKE -- IF
THEY WERE TRYING THE CASE ONLINE
BASICALLY.
AND IT JUST BECAME THIS MASSIVE
CALL TO ACTION.
>> LET'S TAKE A SHORT BREAK.
I WANT TO COME BACK AND TALK
ABOUT THIS FACT.
53 EXCAN YOU SAECUTIONS SINCE T
WERE RELEASED.
WHAT DO YOU THINK ABOUT THAT,
GIVEN THAT YOU WOULD HAVE BEEN
ONE OF THEM?
TO THE BEST VACATION
SPOT ON EARTH.
(ALL) THE GULF!
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHICH OF
OUR GREAT STATES FOLKS VISIT.
MISSISSIPPI,
ALABAMA,
LOUISIANA
OR FLORIDA,
THEY'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
SHAUL, YOUR ALABAMA
HOSPITALITY IS INCREDIBLE.
THANKS, KAREN.
LOVE YOUR MISSISSIPPI OUTDOORS.
I VOTE FOR YOUR
FLORIDA BEACHES, DAWN.
BILL, THIS LOUISIANA
SEAFOOD IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR ON THE GULF,
WE'VE DECIDED TO PUT
ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
NOW IS THE PERFECT TIME TO
VISIT ANYONE OF OUR STATES.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE, GO FISHING
OR JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
WE'VE GOT COASTLINE TO EXPLORE
AND WILDLIFE TO PHOTOGRAPH.
AND THERE'S WORLD CLASS DINING
WITH OUR WORLD FAMOUS SEAFOOD.
SO FOR A GREAT VACATION
THIS YEAR, COME TO THE GULF.
ITS ALL FABULOUS BUT
I GIVE FLORIDA THE EDGE.
RIGHT AFTER MISSISSIPPI.
YOU MEAN ALABAMA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
THIS INVITATION IS
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP
AND ALL OF US WHO
CALL THE GULF HOME.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Capella University understands
back from rough economic times.
Employees are being forced to do
more with less.
And the need for capable leaders
is greater than ever.
When you see these problems do
you take a step back,
or do you want to dive right in?
With a degree in business from
Capella University, you'll have
the knowledge to go further in
your career than you ever
thought possible.
Let's get started at CAPELLA.EDU
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
At Schwab, we're committed
to offering you
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
low-cost investment options--
like our Exchange
Traded Funds, or ETFs
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
which now have the lowest
operating expenses
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
in their respective
Lipper categories.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Lower than SPDR
and even lower than Vanguard.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
That means with Schwab,
your portfolio has
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
a better chance to grow.
And you can trade
all our ETFs online,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
commission-free, from your
Schwab account.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
So let's talk about
saving money,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
with Schwab ETFs.
Schwab ETFs now have the lowest
operating expenses
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
in their respective
Lipper categories.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Call 1-800-4SCHWAB
or visit Schwab.com
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
to open an account today.
Funding is easy
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
with Schwab Mobile Deposit.
Investors should consider
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
carefully information
D#: 1-800-345-2550
contained in the prospectus,
cluding investment objectives,
D#: 1-800-345-2550
risks, charges, and expenses.
You can obtain
D#: 1-800-345-2550
a prospectus by visiting
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
w.schwab.com/schwabetfs.
Please read the prospectus
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
carefully before investing.
>>> WE THE JURY FIND DAMIEN
ECHOLS GUILTY OF CAPITAL MURDER
IN THE DEATH OF STEVIE BRANCH,
CHRIS BIERS AND MICHAEL MOORE.
>> THE VERDICT THAT SENT DAMIEN
ECHOLS TO DEATH ROW.
THEY WERE RELEASED LAST YEAR I'M
BACK WITH DAMIEN, HIS WIFE AND
THE DIRECTOR AMY BERG.
THE DOCUMENTARY, YOU CAN'T WATCH
THAT WITHOUT SHAKING YOUR HEAD
REALLY ABOUT THE LIFE THAT
HAPPENED FOR YOU FOR NEARLY TWO
DECADES.
IT'S A COMPLETELY WASTED LIFE
UNTIL THE STAGE OF WHERE YOU ARE
NOW.
REALLY SHOCKING.
THE OTHER SHOCKING THING, OF
COURSE, YOU COULD HAVE BEEN
EXECUTED BY NOW.
>> RIGHT.
>> 53 PEOPLE HAVE BEEN EXECUTED
SINCE YOU WERE RELEASED.
11 IN 2011, 42 THIS YEAR.
WHEN YOU HEAR THAT, GIVEN YOUR
KNOWLEDGE AND EXPERIENCE OF
DEATH ROW, GIVEN WHAT WE NOW
KNOW ABOUT  WHAT WE NOW
KNOW ABOUT DNA WITH AND THE WAY
IT'S BEEN EXONERATING MANY
PEOPLE ON DEATH ROW, WHAT DO YOU
THINK OF IT?
>> IT'S ABSOLUTELY NIGHTMARISH.
YOU KNOW, THERE'S A LOT OF CASES
OUT THERE THAT DON'T HAVE DNA
THAT THE PEOPLE COULD VERY WELL
BE INNOCENT AND EVEN IF THEY'RE
NOT, YOU KNOW WBT MEDIA SORT OF
PORTRAYS THIS IMAGE TO SOCIETY
THAT DEATH ROW IS FULL OF, YOU
KNOW, CRIMINAL GENIUS HAN BELL
HANNIBAL LEKTER TYPE AND THEY
ARE NOT.
THEY SAY THEY DON'T EXECUTE THE
MENTALLY INSANE OR MENTALLY
HANDICAP AND THEY DO.
>> HOW MANY PEOPLE DID YOU
ENCOUNTER ON DEATH ROW THAT YOU
BASICALLY BELIEVE MAY HAVE BEEN
INNOCENT?
>> I WOULD SAY IN THE TIME WAYS
THERE PROBABLY THREE OTHERS.
ONE WAS EXECUTED, PROBABLY WILL
BE EXECUTED IN THE UPCOMING
YEAR.
ONE HAS A SLIGHT CHANCE OF
GETTING OUT DUE TO THE FACT THAT
THERE HAS BEEN A LITTLE MEDIA
INTEREST IN HIS CASE.
>> WHAT DNA EVIDENCE HAD IT BEEN
AROUND WHEN YOU WERE ARRESTED,
HAVE CLEARED YOU FROM THE START?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
BECAUSE THEY WANTED TO CONVICT
US SO BADLY.
WE HAD OTHER THINGS LIKE ALIBIS,
PEOPLE THAT COULD TESTIFY TO
WHERE WE WERE AT THE TIME AND
CAN PLAINLY PROVE THAT WE
WEREN'T AT THE CRIME SCENE.
THEY SEEN HAVE JESSE MESCELLI
SIGNING A LOG BOOK AND PHOTOS
ABOUT HIM.
SO TECHNICALLY IT IS POSSIBLE
THAT THEY COULD HAVE SHOWED THEM
THE DNA AND THEY WERE SO ENRAGED
AT THE TIME THAT THEY WOULD HAVE
CONVICTED US ANYWAY.
>> HAVE YOU TATTOOS THAT YOU
DIDN'T HAVE LAST TIME.
WHAT DO ME MEAN?
>> IT HELPS ME DEAL.
IT IS VERY PSYCHOLOGICALLY AND
EMOTIONALLY SOOTHING TO ME.
IT IS ALSO LIKE PUTTING ON A
SUIT OF ARMOR.
LIKE IT GIVES YOU SOME SORT OF
LEVEL OF -- LIKE A BUFFER ZONE
BETWEEN YOU AND THE REST OF THE
WORLD.
>> WHAT ARE THE ONES ON YOUR
KNUCKLES?
>> THESE ARE RUINS.
USUALLY WHEN I GET TATTOOS I GET
SOMETHING MEANINGFUL TO ME.
LIKE I SAID, IT IS A SUST ARMOR
SO I LOOK TO PUT ON A SUIT OF
ARMOR MADE OUT OF THINGS I LOVE.
LIKE WINTER, SNOW, ARCH ANGEL
MICHAEL.
SOMETHING THAT MEANS SOMETHING
TO ME PERSONALLY.
>> DO YOU STAY IN TOUCH WITH
JASON AND JESSE?
>> JASON AND I, I HATE MORE THAN
ANYTHING TALKING ON THE PHONE.
BUT WE WILL TEXT.
JESSE, FROM WHAT I HEARD,
DOESN'T HAVE MUCH CONTACT WITH
ANYONE.
HE ONLY HAD A 68 IQ TO BEGIN
WITH AND THEN YOU DUMP ON THIS.
THEY MADE SURE HE WON'T LIVE
ANYTHING REMOTELY RESEMBLING A
NORMAL LIFE.
AND HE IS A SHUT-IN.
>> IT IS A HEART BREAKING STORY,
AS WELL AS SHOCKING STORY.
THESE ARE THREE LIVED VIRTUALLY
RUINS AND MAYBE IN JESSE'S CASE,
COMPLETELY RUINED.
>> I FELL LIKE WEST OF MEMPHIS
IS A BEAUTIFUL LOVE STORY AND I
FEEL LIKE WE HAD BEAUTIFUL
EXCLUSIVE ACCESS TO THE INSIDE
STORY OF THE INVESTIGATION AND
THE LOVE STORY AND I FEEL LIKE,
THAT'S THE HAPPY ENDING THAT
PEOPLE ARE LOOKING FOR IN THIS
STORY.
IS TO SEE HOW IT ACTUALLY
HAPPENED THAT THEY ALL CAME OUT.
>> THIS IS THE WORST THING ABOUT
WHAT YOU'VE BEEN THROUGH, IS
THERE WILL BE A LOT OF PEOPLE
STILL SAY, WELL, THERE'S NO
SMOKE WITHOUT FIRE.
THEY HAVEN'T CAUGHT THE REAL
KILLER.
THIS IS THE TERRIBLE STIGMA YOU
CARRY WITH YOU.
>> IT IS.
AND IT WILL HANG OVER OUR HEADS.
I HATE TALKING ABOUT THIS.
HAVING TO TALK ABOUT THE CASE
DAY AFTER DAY.
IT IS ABSOLUTELY MISERABLE TO
ME.
I ALWAYS TELL PEOPLE, IMAGINE
HAVING TO TALK ABOUT THE WORST
THING THAT EVER HAPPENED TO YOU
OVER AND OVER AND OVER.
BUT AT THE SAME TIME, IF WE
DON'T KEEP DOING IT, WE WILL
HAVE THAT STIGMA HANGING O OVER
OUR HEADS.
WE HAVE TO KEEP LETTING THE
STATE OF ARKANSAS KNOW WE'RE NOT
GOING ANYWHERE UNTIL YOU DO THE
RIGHT THING.
>> HOW IMPORTANT TO YOU AND
POWERFUL TO YOU HAS IT BEEN TO
HAVE LORI'S UNEQUIVOCAL BACKING
AND SUPPORT TO YOU.
>> I COULDN'T HAVE SURVIVED IN
PRISON AND OUT OF PRISON WITHOUT
HER.
WHEN I CON TAKE ANOTHER STEP
WHEN I FELT LIKE I COULDN'T GO
ON, IT WAS HER.
SHE IS WHAT WOULD CARRY ME
FORWARD, MENTALLY, EMOTIONALLY,
SPIRITUALLY UNTIL I COULD WALK
AGAIN.
>> IT IS GOOD TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
>> THANK YOU.
>> I WISH YOU THE VERY BEST, ALL
OF YOU, WITH THE DOCUMENTARY.
IT IS A VERY POWERFUL FILM.
I URGE PEOPLE TO SEE IT.
THEY STILL HAVE NO REAL IDEA
WHAT THIS IS ALL ABOUT, AND TO
UNDERSTAND JUST HOW FAR YOU'VE
COME AND WHAT YOU'VE HAD TO GO
THROUGH.
IT IS CALLED "WEST OF MEM KWPHI
COMING OUT DECEMBER.
THE CD COMES OUT IN JANUARY.
YOUR BOOK IS OUT NOW.
>> THANK YOU.
OBLIGATIONS, BUT OBLIGATIONS.
I NEED TO RETHINK THE
CORE OF MY PORTFOLIO.
WHAT I REALLY NEED IS SLEEP.
INTRODUCING THE ISHARES CORE,
BUILDING BLOCKS FOR THE
HEART OF YOUR PORTFOLIO.
FIND OUT WHY 9 OUT OF 10
LARGE PROFESSIONAL INVESTORS
CHOOSE ISHARES FOR THEIR ETFS.
ISHARES BY BLACKROCK.
CALL 1-800-ISHARES FOR A
PROSPECTUS WHICH INCLUDES
INVESTMENT OBJECTIVES,
RISKS, CHARGES AND EXPENSES.
READ AND CONSIDER
IT CAREFULLY
BEFORE INVESTING.
RISK INCLUDES POSSIBLE
LOSS OF PRINCIPAL.
Every human being
is unique.
And there is one store
that recognizes it.
The Sleep Number Store.
The only place in the
world you'll find the
extraordinarily comfortable
Sleep Number Experience.
An exclusive collection of
innovations that totally
individualize your sleep.
Perfectly comfortable
pillows that adjust to
your size and shape.
Temperature-balancing
bedding.
Dual warmth comforters.
All designed around the
Sleep Number Bed: A bed
with dual-air technology
that allows you to adjust
to the support your
body needs.
Each of your bodies.
In the name of human
individuality: The Sleep
Number Collection.
Discover how our sleep
professionals can
individualize your sleep
experience.
Exclusively at one of our 400
Sleep Number Stores nationwide.
Sleep Number.
Comfort Individualized.
This holiday season, give
the gift that's magical:
the innovative AirFit
adjustable pillow at
special 30% savings.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] WHILE YOU'RE
GETTING READY FOR THE HOLIDAYS,
WE'RE GETTING READY FOR YOU.
TIS THE SEASON.
FOR FOOD, FOR FAMILY,
AND NOW, SOMETHING EXTRA --
FOR YOU.
>>> TOMORROW NIGHT, ONE OF MY
FAVORITE INTERVIEWS SINCE I
JOINED CNN NEARLY TWO YEARS AGO,
A CONVERSATION WITH BARBRA
STREISAND, AN HOUR WITH ONE OF
THE GREATEST ENTERTAINERS IN
HISTORY.
SHE IS A TRUE ICON AND SHE TALKS
WITH REMARKABLE CANDOR ABOUT HER
PUBLIC AND PRIVATE LIFE.
HER RELATIONSHIPS WITH MANY
PEOPLE, INCLUDING MARLON BRANDO.
HERE IS A PREVIEW.
>> WE ONCE WENT ON A SHORT ROAD
TRIP TOGETHER.
>> YOU AND MARLON BRANDO?
>> MM-HM.
>> THIS IS FANTASTIC.
WHERE DID YOU GO?
>> HE WANTED TO TAKE ME TO THE
DESERT TO