TO WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT MY
FAMILY AND MY WIFE AND MY
DAUGHTERS ARE TAKEN CARE OF AND
THAT IF THERE'S ANYTHING THAT I
CAN DO TO HELP ANYBODY AT ANY
TIME, ANYWHERE, I'D BE WILLING
TO DO THAT.
AS WE MOVE ON FROM WHAT HAPPENED
HERE, WHAT HAPPENED TO SO MANY
PEOPLE, LET IT NOT TURN INTO
SOMETHING THAT DEFINES US, BUT
SOMETHING THAT INSPIRES US TO BE
BETTER, TO BE MORE COMPASSIONATE
AND MORE HUMBLE PEOPLE.
>> A FATHER, A FAMILY, A
COMMUNITY IN GRIEF.
THEIR HEARTS ARE HEAVY.
>>> GOOD EVENING, EVERYONE.
FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, I'M
ANDERSON COOPER BACK FOR A
SPECIAL EDITION OF "360"
TONIGHT.
THIS IS THE SMALL TOWN WHERE
THIS CRIME SHOCKED THE ENTIRE
NATION JUST ONE DAY AGO.
POLICE TONIGHT ARE STILL COMBING
THROUGH WHAT THEY CALL EVERY
CRACK AND CREVICE.
THOSE ARE THEIR WORDS, OF THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WHERE A GUNMAN
SHOT 26 PEOPLE, MOST OF THEM 6
AND 7-YEAR-OLDS.
THEY'RE ALSO AT THE HOME OF THE
MAN IDENTIFIED AS THE SHOOTER,
TRYING TO LEARN ANY CLUES THEY
CAN ABOUT WHY HE DID WHAT HE
DID, WHY THIS SCHOOL IN
PARTICULAR.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL BE HERE
TOMORROW VISITING THE FAMILIES
OF THE VICTIMS, THE 20 KIDS AND
THE SIX ADULTS KILLED IN THE
SCHOOL.
ALSO TALKING TO FIRST RESPONDERS
AND TALKING AT A PRAYER VIGIL
TOMORROW EVENING.
WE ARE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THOSE
YOUNG VICTIMS TONIGHT, THOSE 12
GIRLS AND EIGHT LITTLE BOYS SHOT
DEAD IN THEIR CLASSROOMS.
MOST OF WHAT WE'RE LEARNING IS
FROM THEIR PARENTS WHO ARE
SHARING THEIR GRIEF VERY
PUBLICLY TONIGHT.
KYUNG LAH, YOU WERE THERE
EARLIER WHEN THE FATHER OF
EMILIE PARKER CAME OUT OF HIS
HOUSE AND WANTED TO TELL PEOPLE,
WANTED TO TALK TO TV CAMERAS AND
JUST TALK IN A VERY HUMAN WAY
ABOUT HIS DAUGHTER, ABOUT WHAT
SHE WAS LIKE, ABOUT THE LIFE SHE
LIVED.
>> AND HE WAS VERY CLEAR THAT
THE REASON HE WANTED TO COME OUT
AND FACE CAMERAS -- HE KNOWS
THIS IS NATIONAL TELEVISION, HE
WANTED TO MAKE SURE THAT PEOPLE
ACROSS THE COUNTRY KNEW THAT HE
WANTED TO SAY THANK YOU AND HE
ALSO WANTED TO SHARE A MESSAGE,
THAT WE'RE BETTER THAN THIS,
THAT SOCIETY CANNOT BE DEFINED
BY THIS SINGLE ACT.
HE LOST A 6-YEAR-OLD GIRL.
AND IT'S ONE THING TO THINK
ABOUT THE NUMBER.
IT'S A TOTALLY DIFFERENT THING
TO WATCH THIS MAN TALK, TO LOOK
AT THE PICTURES OF THIS
BEAUTIFUL GIRL AND TO FULLY
COMPREHEND THAT THIS FAMILY HAS
SUFFERED A TRUE, TRUE LOSS.
HERE'S WHAT HE TOLD US.
>> I WAS LEAVING TO WORK, AND
SHE WOKE UP BEFORE I LEFT.
AND I'VE ACTUALLY BEEN TEACHING
HER PORTUGUESE.
SO OUR LAST CONVERSATION WAS IN
PORTUGUESE.
SHE TOLD ME GOOD MORNING.
AND ASKED HOW I WAS DOING.
AND I SAID THAT I WAS DOING
WELL.
SHE SAID THAT SHE LOVED ME AND I
GAVE HER A KISS AND I WAS OUT
THE DOOR.
AS THE DEEP PAIN BEGINS TO
SETTLE INTO OUR HEARTS, WE FIND
COMFORT REFLECTING ON THE
INCREDIBLE PERSON THAT EMILIE
WAS AND HOW MANY LIVES THAT SHE
WAS ABLE TO TOUCH IN HER SHORT
TIME HERE ON EARTH.
EMILIE WAS BRIGHT, CREATIVE AND
VERY LOVING.
MY DAUGHTER EMILIE WOULD BE ONE
OF THE FIRST ONES TO BE STANDING
AND GIVING HER LOVE AND SUPPORT
TO ALL THOSE VICTIMS BECAUSE
THAT'S THE TYPE OF PERSON THAT
SHE IS, NOT BECAUSE OF ANY
PARENTING THAT MY WIFE AND I
COULD HAVE DONE BUT BECAUSE
THOSE WERE THE GIFTS THAT WERE
GIVEN TO HER BY HER HEAVENLY
FATHER.
>> AND HE ALSO SAID THAT HE WAS
VERY PROUD TO BE HER FATHER,
THAT HE WAS GOING TO BE THE BEST
FATHER HE COULD TO HIS TWO
REMAINING CHILDREN, A 3-YEAR-OLD
AND A 4-YEAR-OLD GIRL, HER
SISTERS.
HE DID ALSO SAY THAT HE WANTED
TO MAKE SURE THAT HE EXTENDED
HIS CONDOLENCES TO THE SHOOTER'S
FAMILY BECAUSE THEY ALSO
SUFFERED A LOSS, ANDERSON.
AND THE THING THAT'S REALLY
EXTRAORDINARY IS HOW HE'S ABLE
TO GET HIS MESSAGE OUT AND STILL
KEEP IT TOGETHER.
IT'S REALLY -- IT'S HARD TO
WATCH AND TO COMPREHEND.
>> HOW DOES A FATHER TELL A 3
AND A 4-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER THAT
THEIR SISTER, THEIR BIG SISTER
IS GONE?
IT'S JUST INCREDIBLE.
KYUNG LAH, APPRECIATE YOU
REPORTING TONIGHT.
RESIDENTS OF STRATFORD,
CONNECTICUT, REMEMBER VICTORIA
SOTO WHO GREW UP THERE.
SHE WAS 27 YEARS OLD.
SHE TAUGHT FIRST GRADE AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY.
THEY WERE WEARING THOSE COLORS
BECAUSE THAT WAS HER FAVORITE
COLOR, GREEN.
JASON CARROLL JOINS ME NOW, MORE
ON THE VIGIL.
SOUNDS AS THOUGH THE COMMUNITY
REALLY ADORED THAT TEACHER AND
TONIGHT WANTED TO KIND OF SHOW
THAT IN A VERY PUBLIC WAY.
>> YOU'RE EXACTLY RIGHT,
ANDERSON.
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED
HERE TONIGHT.
THE FAMILY SAYING THAT IT
BASICALLY ALL STARTED ON
FACEBOOK WITH A FACEBOOK
MESSAGE, LET'S GET TOGETHER,
LET'S FIND OUT A WAY TO HONOR
VICTORIA, VICKI, AS HER FAMILY
AND FRIENDS CALLED HER.
VICTORIA SOTO.
THAT'S WHAT THEY DID.
THEY CAME OUT HERE TONIGHT IN
FRONT OF HER HIGH SCHOOL.
THIS IS WHERE EVERYONE KNEW HER.
EVERYONE WAS TALKING ABOUT HER
SAYING SHE WANTED TO BE A
TEACHER EVER SINCE SHE WAS A
LITTLE GIRL AND THEY TALKED
ABOUT HOW DEDICATED THIS YOUNG
WOMAN WAS TO HER STUDENTS.
IN FACT, SHE DIDN'T EVEN REFER
TO THEM AS STUDENTS.
SHE ALWAYS REFERRED TO THEM AS
HER KIDS, HER CHILDREN.
AND OUT HERE TONIGHT, AS YOU CAN
IMAGINE WITH HER SISTER BEING
HERE, HER BROTHER BEING HERE,
HER PARENTS BEING HERE, HER
COUSIN HERE AS WELL, AS EVERYONE
GATHERED TOGETHER AND HUGGED
EACH OTHER, THEY STRUGGLED TO
FIND WAYS TO REMEMBER HER.
I SPOKE TO ONE YOUNG WOMAN WHO
KNEW VICKI SOTA THROUGHOUT HER
ENTIRE LIFE.
LISTEN TO HOW SHE SPOKE ABOUT
HER TONIGHT.
>> SHE WAS ALWAYS AT THE HOUSE
SMILING.
SHE DROVE US TO CHEERLEADING
PRACTICES A COUPLE OF TIMES.
I'M ALSO A TEACHER AND I CAN'T
EVEN IMAGINE GOING THROUGH WHAT
SHE WENT THROUGH.
I THINK HER PUTTING HERSELF OUT
THERE -- SHE'S JUST AN ANGEL AND
SHE JUST WENT STRAIGHT INTO
HEAVEN.
THERE'S NO DOUBT ABOUT THAT.
>> AS YOU CAN SEE, ANDERSON,
OBVIOUSLY IT'S AN EMOTIONAL
STRUGGLE FOR SO MANY PEOPLE OUT
HERE TONIGHT.
AT ONE MOMENT, CARLEY SOTO,
SHE'S 19 YEARS OLD, SHE STOOD IN
FRONT OF THE SEVERAL HUNDRED
PEOPLE WHO GATHERED OUT HERE
TONIGHT AND SHE SPOKE JUST
BRIEFLY, JUST FOR A MOMENT SHE
REMINDED THE AUDIENCE TO HUG
YOUR LOVED ONES BECAUSE YOU JUST
NEVER KNOW WHEN YOU'RE EVER
GOING TO SEE THEM AGAIN.
IT WAS A VERY POWERFUL MOMENT AS
THE FAMILY PAID TRIBUTE TO A
WOMAN WHO THEY SAY WAS A
DEDICATED TEACHER, A LOVING
DAUGHTER AND SOMEONE WHO LOVED
HER CHILDREN OR HER STUDENTS.
ANDERSON?
>> ONE FAMILY SAYS THEY OWE
THEIR SON'S LIFE TO VICKI SOTO.
THEY SPOKE WITH KATE BOLDUAN
ABOUT THEIR CHILD'S ORDEAL
YESTERDAY AND HOW SHE'S COPING
WITH WHAT HE'S SEEN.
>> ROBERT AND DIANE LIKATA HAD
TWO CHILDREN AT THAT ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL YESTERDAY, A
SECOND-GRADER AND THEIR SON IN
FIRST GRADE WHO THEY SAY IT IS A
MIRACLE HE MADE IT OUT ALIVE
AFTER COMING FACE TO FACE WITH
THE SHOOTER.
>> THAT'S WHEN THEY HEARD NOISES
THAT THEY INITIALLY THOUGHT WERE
HAMMERS FALLING.
THEN THEY REALIZED THAT IT WAS
GUNSHOTS.
AND MS. SOTO, WHO WAS ADEN'S
TEACHER, HAD THE PRESENCE OF
MIND TO MOVE ALL THE CHILDREN TO
A DISTANCE AWAY FROM THE DOOR ON
THE SIDE OF THE ROOM FURTHEST
AWAY FROM THE DOOR.
THAT'S WHEN THE GUNMAN BURST IN,
DID NOT SAY A WORD, NO FACIAL
EXPRESSIONS, AND PROCEEDED TO
SHOOT THEIR TEACHER.
AND THEY BASICALLY RAN RIGHT
NEXT TO THE GUY AND OUT THE
DOOR.
>> THEY RAN PAST THE GUNMAN.
>> THEY RAN PAST THE GUY.
HE'S STILL STANDING IN THE DOOR
AND THEY RAN PAST HIM AND RAN
DOWN THE HALLWAY AND THEY'RE ONE
OF THE CLOSEST ROOMS TO THE MAIN
ENTRANCE.
AND ADEN WAS -- HAD THE PRESENCE
OF MIND TO HOLD THE DOOR FOR ONE
OF HIS CLASSMATES.
THERE WAS ANOTHER ONE OF HIS
CLASSMATES THAT WAS A LITTLE
BEHIND.
WAITED FOR HIM AND THEY RAN OUT
TO THE MAIN ROAD.
>> WE KNOW HIS TEACHER, VICTORIA
SOTO, DIED IN THAT CLASSROOM
TRYING TO PROTECT HER STUDENTS.
HE KNOWS HIS TEACHER WAS SHOT.
DO YOU THINK HE KNOWS THAT SHE
LIKELY DID NOT MAKE IT?
>> HE KEEPS ASKING ABOUT HER.
I THINK HE'S REASSURING HIMSELF
THAT SHE'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
HE REALLY, REALLY CARED ABOUT
HIS TEACHER.
HE WAS VERY CLOSE WITH HER.
AND SHE REALLY LOVED THAT CLASS.
AND HE KEEPS SAYING, I REALLY
HOPE SHE'S OKAY, I HOPE IT'S NOT
HER.
HE KNOWS THAT SHE'S BEEN HURT
BUT HE DOESN'T KNOW THE END
RESULT.
HE KNOWS THE KIDS THAT HE SAW
GETTING SHOT.
HE DOESN'T KNOW THE OUTCOME.
SO I THINK HE'S REASSURING
HIMSELF IN HIS 6-YEAR-OLD MIND.
I KNOW HE'S PROCESSING IT.
BUT I THINK HE'S REASSURING
HIMSELF.
I THINK HE'S TELLING HIMSELF
THAT IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
WE HAD TO PUT THE SIGN OUT IN
THE FRONT TODAY ASKING PEOPLE
NOT TO RING THE DOORBELL BECAUSE
HE STILL HASN'T INTERNALIZED THE
FACT THAT THIS GUNMAN, THIS BAD
GUY IS GONE.
AND HE WANTS TO KNOW IF THERE
ARE MORE BAD GUYS IN THE WORLD.
AND I DON'T KNOW HOW TO ANSWER
THAT QUESTION PROPERLY AND SO
WHEN SOMEONE RINGS THE DOORBELL,
HE THINKS IT'S HIM COMING
BACK -- COMING FOR HIM.
AND SO HE -- SO I THINK OUR
BIGGEST CONCERN NOW IS MAKING
SURE THAT WE HANDLE HIS
SENSITIVE NATURE PROPERLY AND
CAREFULLY AND SUPPORT HIM AND
SUPPORT OUR DAUGHTER BECAUSE SHE
AGAIN DOES PROCESS THINGS VERY
DIFFERENTLY THAN HE DOES.
SO THAT'S OUR JOB AS PARENTS NOW
IS TO STAY CLOSE TO THEM, HOLD
THEM, HUG THEM, LOVE THEM AND
LET THEM KNOW THAT THEY ARE
SAFE.
>> THEY DID NOT WANT THEIR
CHILDREN TO BE PART OF THE
INTERVIEW.
BUT I DID SPEND TIME WITH THEM
THIS MORNING.
AND ADEN AND HIS SISTER, THEY
SEEMED IN HIGH SPIRITS.
BUT CLEARLY SHAKEN.
AND AS HARD AS IT HAS BEEN FOR
THIS FAMILY, THEY SAY THAT THEIR
HEARTS GO OUT TO THE SO MANY
OTHER FAMILIES WHO CANNOT GO
HOME AND HUG THEIR CHILDREN
TONIGHT.
ANDERSON?
>> KATE THANK YOU.
ONE OF THE BUSIEST PLACES IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, TODAY MAY
HAVE BEEN THE GRIEF COUNSELING
CENTER, BOTH VICTIMS AND THOSE
AFFECTED BY WHAT HAPPENED FRIDAY
GOT THE CHANCE TO SPEAK TO
SOMEONE IF THEY WANTED ABOUT
WHAT THEY WERE FEELING.
FOR SOME, THE HEALING COMES IN
HONORING THOSE VICTIMS.
ALL DAY LONG, PEOPLE HAVE BEEN
CREATING GIANT MEMORIALS TO
THOSE WHO WERE KILLED.
I'M JOINED NOW BY DR. SANJAY
GUPTA WHO WAS AT THAT COUNSELING
CENTER EARLIER.
WE'RE LOOKING AT A PICTURE THERE
OF ONE OF THE MAKESHIFT
MEMORIALS THAT'S SPRUNG UP, SO
OFTEN SPRUNG UP IN TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS.
PEOPLE SPONTANEOUSLY EXPRESSING
THEIR SORROW, EXPRESSING THEIR
GRIEF AND THEIR REMEMBRANCES IN
WAYS LARGE AND SMALL.
YOU'VE ACTUALLY BEEN LOOKING AT
STUDIES ABOUT HOW KIDS IN THIS
AGE RANGE, YOUNG KIDS, DEAL WITH
WITNESSING A TRAUMATIC EVENT.
>> FIRST OF ALL, PTSD IS
SOMETHING WE TYPICALLY THINK OF
WITH ADULTS.
WE DON'T TALK ABOUT THEM WITH
CHILDREN VERY MUCH AND CERTAINLY
CHILDREN THIS YOUNG.
IT EXISTS VERY MUCH SO THE WAY
THAT THEY -- THEIR BEHAVIOR IS
DIFFERENT.
THEY DON'T HAVE THE FLASHBACKS,
THE SORT OF HYPERVIGILANCE THAT
WE ASSOCIATE WITH PTSD.
OFTENTIMES YOU SEE IT IN THE WAY
THEY PLAY, SOMETIMES YOU SEE IT
IN THE WAY THAT THEY REGRESS.
THEY MAY START ACTING YOUNGER.
THEY MAY BE MORE CLINGY.
THEY MAY HAVE TEMPER TANTRUMS OR
BEHAVIOR THAT SEEMS OUT OF
SORTS.
OFTENTIMES, CAREGIVERS DON'T
KNOW WHAT TO MAKE OF IT.
>> DOES IT SORT OF -- THE
TIMETABLE, DOES IT PLAY OUT
IMMEDIATELY OR IS IT SOMETHING
THAT SHOWS MONTHS LATER?
>> NO, IT OFTEN SHOWS UP VERY
EARLY.
THAT WAS A VERY IMPORTANT POINT
BECAUSE IF YOU NOTICE IT EARLY,
THAT'S PRETTY NORMAL FOR BOTH
ADULTS AND CHILDREN ALIKE.
IF IT TURNS INTO NIGHTMARES,
ANXIETY OR LOSS OF SLEEP, THAT'S
WHEN USUALLY IT'S TIME TO TRY
AND MAYBE GET SOME HELP.
WE TALKED ABOUT THIS A LITTLE
BIT LAST NIGHT, ANDERSON.
BUT IF YOU LOOK AT THE STUDY
SPECIFICALLY ON SLEEP, IT'S
COMPELLING STUFF.
IF SOMEBODY GETS GOOD SLEEP,
GOOD QUALITY SLEEP, YOU CAN
PREDICT MUCH MORE ACCURATELY HOW
WELL THEY'RE GOING TO BE ABLE TO
COPE IN THE LONG RUN.
AND THAT SLEEP IN THE FIRST FEW
NIGHTS, LAST NIGHT, TONIGHT,
PARENTS WATCHING THEIR CHILD'S
SLEEP PATTERNS TONIGHT IS REALLY
IMPORTANT.
>> DEFINITELY FASCINATING.
SOMETHING WE TALKED ABOUT A
COUPLE OF HOURS AGO, I THINK IT
BEARS REPEATING BECAUSE I THINK
IT HAS CONCERNED A LOT OF
PARENTS, PARENTS WHOSE KIDS ARE
ON THE SPECTRUM OF AUTISM OR
HAVE ASPERGER'S.
YESTERDAY THERE HAD BEEN A QUOTE
FROM THE BROTHER OF THE SHOOTER
WHO THOUGHT HIS BROTHER HAD A
FORM OF AUTISM AND ALSO A
PERSONALITY DISORDER.
AUTISM IS NOT A PERSONALITY
DISORDER.
LET'S CLARIFY --
>> YES, AS YOU ALWAYS SAY, TERMS
DO MATTER HERE.
WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT AUTISM OR
ANYTHING ON THE AUTISM SPECTRUM
AS THEY CALL IT, IT'S A
NEURODEVELOPMENTAL DISORDER.
IT'S SOMETHING THAT HAPPENED IN
THE BRAIN SINCE TIME OF BIRTH.
THAT'S GOING TO BE DIFFERENT
THAN A PERSONALITY DISORDER OR
EVEN A MENTAL ILLNESS WHICH
COULD COME ON LATER IN LIFE.
BUT THE MORE CRUCIAL POINT IS
IT'S NOT ASSOCIATED WITH SORT OF
PLANNED VIOLENCE.
IT JUST ISN'T.
>> I'VE NEVER HEARD OF A YOUNG
PERSON WITH AUTISM COMMITTING A
PREPLANNED ACT OF VIOLENCE.
>> I HADN'T EITHER.
BUT I WENT AND LOOKED AT THE
STUDIES AGAIN.
THE STUDY THAT EVERYONE QUOTES
IS A STUDY OF ABOUT 132 PEOPLE,
THAT'S NOT A HUGE STUDY BUT IT'S
ONE OF THE BIGGEST STUDIES OUT
THERE.
OF THOSE 132, THERE WERE ONLY
THREE SORT OF EPISODES OF
VIOLENCE.
AS YOU MENTIONED, NONE OF THEM
PREPLANNED.
THERE'S NO LINK.
I THINK I CAN SAFELY SAY THERE'S
NO LINK BETWEEN AUTISM SPECTRUM
AND PREPLANNED VIOLENCE.
WE CAN DISPEL THAT --
>> THERE ARE SO MANY KIDS WHO
ARE NOW DIAGNOSED SOMEWHERE ON
THE AUTISM SPECTRUM.
I'VE HEARD FROM A LOT OF
PARENTS, OUTRAGED THAT PEOPLE
ARE USING THE TERM AUTISM AND
LINKING IT SOMEHOW TO THE
SHOOTING.
YOU JUST CLARIFIED --
>> I HOPE THEY'RE WATCHING.
I THINK IT'S AN EDUCATIONAL
POINT.
THAT'S JUST NOT TRUE.
>> WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO BE KIND
OF -- WHAT SHOULD PARENTS BE
WATCHING FOR, DO YOU THINK, IN
THE NEXT COUPLE OF DAYS?
>> I THINK THERE IS A -- THERE'S
A LOT OF NORMAL SORT OF GRIEF
THAT'S GOING ON.
I THINK OBVIOUSLY WITH CHILDREN,
IT'S NOT GOING TO BE SORT OF THE
THING -- IT'S NOT GOING TO BE
THE THINGS YOU MIGHT EXPECT.
ADULTS HAVE A MUCH BETTER WAY OF
VERBALIZING THESE THINGS.
I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT FOR
PARENTS TO NOW AND A LOT OF
EXPERTS HAVE BEEN SAYING THIS.
BUT THIS IS NORMAL IN THE FIRST
FEW DAYS.
WHAT HAPPENS IS THAT IF IT
PROGRESSES LONGER TERM, THEN
PEOPLE DO NEED TO GET HELP.
THERE IS HELP AVAILABLE HERE,
PHONE LINES BUT ALSO A GRIEF
CENTER AVAILABLE.
IF IT'S PERSISTENT, THAT HELP
NEEDS -- THERE'S NOT ENOUGH
THINKING OF MENTAL ILLNESS OR
THESE TYPES OF PROBLEMS WITH
PHYSICAL ILLNESS AS IT IS.
WE TEND TO PUT THESE THINGS IN
DIFFERENT BUCKETS.
THE IDEA THAT YOU THINK ABOUT
MENTAL ILLNESS AS YOU DO IN
CARDIAC DISEASE -- IT'S
STIGMATIZED.
THERE'S NOT ENOUGH RESOURCES.
WE TALK ABOUT IT IN SITUATIONS
LIKE THIS.
BUT HOPEFULLY IT WILL CATCH ON.
>> FOR PARENTS WHO HAVE A CHILD
WITH SOME SORT OF MENTAL
DISORDER -- AND THERE'S A LOT WE
DON'T KNOW ABOUT THIS SHOOTER.
BUT IN PAST CASES, IN THE
VIRGINIA TECH INSTANCE, PARENTS
TRIED TO GET HELP FOR THE CHILD
OR FOR THE YOUNG ADULT.
AND UNLESS THAT PERSON CAN BE
PROVED TO BE VIOLENT OR IS A
THREAT TO THEMSELVES OR SOMEBODY
ELSE, THEY OFTEN CAN'T GET HELP.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
PARENTS CAN ANGUISH OVER THIS.
OFTENTIMES, THEY KNEW THE SIGNS
BUT COULDN'T GET HELP.
YOU MENTIONED VIRGINIA TECH,
THREE MONTHS LATER,
THREE-QUARTERS OF THE STUDENTS
STILL HAD SOME FORM OF PTSD.
THIS CAN LAST QUITE A LONG TIME.
>> THANK YOU, SANJAY.
A LOT MORE AHEAD.
WE'LL TAKE A SHORT BREAK.
YOUR COVERAGE CONTINUES FROM
HERE IN NEWTOWN.
ñç@RÑo
>>> IF YOU'VE BEEN WATCHING A
LOT OF COVERAGE OF THIS TRAGEDY,
YOU NO DOUBT KNOW THE NAME OF
THE SHOOTER BY NOW.
WE ARE NOT DURING THIS BROADCAST
USING THE NAME OF THE SHOOTER.
YOU PROBABLY ALREADY KNOW,
THERE'S NO NEED TO REPEAT IT
OVER AND OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
OFTEN IT SEEMS THAT IN HISTORY
REMEMBERS THE NAMES OF MURDERERS
AND NOT THE NAMES OF VICTIMS.
AND I THINK THAT'S -- I JUST
THINK THAT IT SHOULDN'T BE.
SO WE'RE TRYING TO DO WHAT WE
CAN TO NOT CONTRIBUTE TO THAT
NAME BEING OUT THERE AND BEING
KNOWN AS A HOUSEHOLD NAME FROM
HERE ON OUT.
WITNESSES TO THE SHOOTING
YESTERDAY SAY THAT THE FIRST
SHOTS RANG OUT AND JUST AS THE
MORNING ANNOUNCEMENTS WERE BEING
READ AT THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
AND POLICE ARE TRYING TO HAMMER
DOWN EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED
BEFORE THAT MOMENT.
TOM FOREMAN BREAKS IT DOWN FOR
US RIGHT NOW WITH WHAT
INVESTIGATORS KNOW SO FAR.
>> POLICE ARE ESSENTIALLY
CONSTRUCTING A MAP OF ALL OF THE
PLACES THAT MIGHT HAVE HAD
CONNECTIONS TO THIS SHOOTER.
FOR EXAMPLE, HIS BROTHER'S
APARTMENT DOWN HERE IN NEW
JERSEY ACROSS NEW YORK UP INTO
CONNECTICUT.
HIS MOTHER'S HOUSE WHERE SHE WAS
FOUND DEAD.
ONLY ABOUT THREE MILES AWAY, OF
COURSE, THE SCHOOL.
TO TRY TO FIGURE OUT WHAT LED
HIM TO THIS SPOT AT THAT TIME
BECAUSE THEY DO BELIEVE THAT
SHORTLY AFTER MURDERING HIS
MOTHER, HE DID DRIVE THE FEW
MILES FROM HER HOUSE TO THIS
SCHOOL AND EMERGE IN THIS
PARKING LOT WITH WEAPONS VERY
MUCH LIKE THESE TO GO INTO THE
SCHOOL.
NOW, LET'S LOOK AT THE TIME LINE
OF WHAT HAPPENED.
THAT'S WHAT THEY'RE TRYING TO
RECONSTRUCT.
ABOUT 9:30 IN THE MORNING,
THAT'S WHEN WE BELIEVE BASED ON
EYEWITNESS ACCOUNTS AND POLICE
RADIO, THAT HE PROBABLY LEFT HIS
CAR, WE THINK THIS IS THE ONE
OVER HERE, BASED ON THE
INVESTIGATION, AND CAME UP TO
THE FRONT OF THE SCHOOL.
IT'S ALSO WHEN HE ENCOUNTERED
HIS FIRST OBSTACLE.
BECAUSE THESE SECURITY DOORS
WERE INSTALLED TO KEEP PEOPLE
OUT.
POLICE LATER SAID THE GLASS HAD
BEEN BROKEN OUT OF THESE.
THAT'S APPARENTLY HOW HE GOT
INTO THE SCHOOL WITH THOSE
WEAPONS.
WHAT WE KNOW FOR SURE IS BASED
ON POLICE REPORTS, BY 9:36, WE
HAD OUR FIRST CALLS INTO THE
POLICE STATION SAYING THAT
SHOOTING WAS OCCURRING INSIDE
THE SCHOOL AND, OF COURSE,
EVERYBODY WITHIN THE SCHOOL WAS
ALERTED TO THE SOUND OF THE
GUNFIRE.
IF THEY DIDN'T HEAR IT DIRECTLY,
THEY HEARD IT OVER THE P.A.
SYSTEM IN THIS SCHOOL WHERE
ANNOUNCEMENTS WERE BEING MADE AT
THAT TIME.
THIS IS ALSO SIGNIFICANT, BY
9:38, 2 TO 2 1/2 MINUTES LATER,
POLICE WERE SAYING IF NOT ALL
THE SHOOTING, A BULK OF THE
SHOOTING WAS OVER, A VERY SHORT
PERIOD OF TIME IN A VERY SMALL
AREA WHERE IT ALL SEEMED TO
OCCUR.
WHAT HAPPENED AFTER THAT?
WELL, IT PROGRESSED EVEN
FURTHER.
BY ABOUT 9:40 IN THE MORNING,
POLICE WERE CALLING FOR
EMERGENCY MEDICAL TECHNICIANS TO
COME THERE, FOR AMBULANCES TO
COME.
A FEW MINUTES LATER, THEY CALLED
FOR A WHOLE LOT MORE AMBULANCES
TO COME.
AND BY 9:50 OR SO IN THE
MORNING, THEY WERE ESSENTIALLY
SAYING THE SCENE WAS SECURE.
THEY HAD A SUSPECT WHO WAS DOWN.
THEY HAD CLEARED THE BUILDING.
THAT MANY OF THE CHILDREN WERE
BEING LED OUT, AS YOU CAN SEE IN
THIS PHOTOGRAPH FROM "THE
NEWTOWN BEE."
AND THAT THE SITUATION WAS MORE
OR LESS SECURE.
THERE IS STILL A LOT OF WORK TO
BE DONE OBVIOUSLY.
BUT AS YOU CAN SEE, AS WE LOOK
AT THIS TIME LINE CLOSER AND
CLOSER, IT'S COMING DOWN TO A
VERY SHORT PERIOD OF TIME, 20
MINUTES OR LESS FROM THE
BEGINNING TO THE END OF THIS IN
TERMS OF PEOPLE REALLY KNOWING
WHAT WAS HAPPENING.
AND NOW THIS HUGE, LONG, LONG
SEARCH TO UNDERSTAND WHY IT
HAPPENED.
ANDERSON?
>> TOM, THANKS VERY MUCH.
WE WANT TO GO TO OUR DAVID
ARIOSTO WHO'S IN THE
NEIGHBORHOOD WHERE THE MOTHER OF
THIS SHOOTER LIVED.
DAVID, WHAT ARE YOU LEARNING
ABOUT THIS LADY?
>> ANDERSON, THIS IS WHERE THAT
FIRST MURDER TOOK PLACE BEFORE
THE SHOOTER HEADED OVER TO THAT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE'VE TALKED TO NEIGHBORS IN AND
AROUND THE AREA HERE.
THEY PAINT A PICTURE OF A WOMAN
WHO WAS KILLED RIGHT BEFORE THAT
SHOOTING -- THEY DESCRIBE HER
SORT OF AS THIS PLEASURABLE
WOMAN, A WOMAN WHO WAS A VERY
PLEASANT PERSON TO BE AROUND.
SOMEONE WHO LOVED GARDENING,
LOVED LANDSCAPING, SOMEONE WHO
ATTENDED A MONTHLY DICE GAME
WITH MANY PEOPLE IN THE
NEIGHBORHOOD.
IT'S A TIGHT-KNIT COMMUNITY IN
THIS SOUTHWESTERN CONNECTICUT
TOWN.
AND EVEN THOUGH YOU CAN'T REALLY
GET A SENSE OF IT NOW, IT IS ONE
OF THE MORE PICTURESQUE PLACES
I'M STANDING IN.
ROLLING GREEN HILLS AND QUITE AN
AFFLUENT NEIGHBORHOOD, TWO AND
THREE-STORY HOMES.
THE THINKING IS PEOPLE MOVED TO
THIS AREA BECAUSE OF THE SCHOOL
SYSTEMS.
SO IT STRIKES A PARTICULAR CHORD
THAT THIS OCCURRED WITHIN AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
BUT THEN YOU ALSO HAVE THAT
OTHER SIDE, THE TALK OF THIS
WOMAN, NANCY LANZA, WHO
COLLECTED GUNS, SOME
HIGH-POWERED WEAPONS AS IN THAT
BUSHMASTER THAT WAS USED IN THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SHOOTING.
IT'S NOT CLEAR WHETHER SHE
ATTENDED SOME OF THE SHOOTING
RANGES IN THE AREA ALTHOUGH WE
KNOW THERE ARE AT LEAST THREE
SHOOTING RANGES WITHIN A 20-MILE
RANGE OF THIS AREA.
ONE OF THE WORKERS THAT I SPOKE
TO AT A LOCAL BUSINESS HERE SAID
THAT SHE OFTEN SHOWED HER
RIFLE -- SHOWED A RIFLE THAT SHE
HAD RECENTLY PURCHASE AND EVEN
BROUGHT HER CHILDREN TARGET
SHOOTING.
NOT CLEAR IF THAT OCCURRED AT
THOSE RANGES OR JUST IN AND
AROUND THE AREA.
ATF AND FEDERAL OFFICIALS WE'VE
SPOKEN TO, FBI, SAID THAT THAT
DIDN'T OCCUR.
THERE'S REALLY QUITE A BIT OF
CONFLICTING INFORMATION AS TO
WHAT TRANSPIRED HERE.
BUT ONE NEIGHBOR PERHAPS SORT OF
SAID IT BEST.
SOMETHING JUST DOESN'T QUITE ADD
UP AS TO WHO THIS WOMAN WAS, WHY
SHE WAS KILLED AND WHAT
TRANSPIRED IN REALLY THE MINUTES
AFTER HER DEATH.
>> YEAH, SO MANY QUESTIONS STILL
UNANSWERED AT THIS POINT.
DAVID, APPRECIATE THE REPORTING.
WE'LL TAKE A SHORT BREAK.
OUR COVERAGE CONTINUES IN A
MOMENT.
>>> IN THIS HOUR AND IN THE DAYS
AHEAD, WE'RE TRYING TO FOCUS AS
MUCH AS WE CAN ON THE VICTIMS
AND LETTING YOU KNOW ABO THE
LIVES THEY LIVED, NOT JUST HOW
THEY LOST THEIR LIVES BUT THE
KIND OF LIVES THEY LIVED, WHO
THEY WERE.
AND TODAY WE'RE ABLE TO TELL YOU
MORE ABOUT THEM THAN WE WERE
YESTERDAY.
AND NO DOUBT TOMORROW WE'LL BE
ABLE TO TELL YOU EVEN MORE AS
FAMILY MEMBERS COME FORWARD AND
WANT TO SHARE THEIR GRIEF AND
WANT TO SHARE THEIR MEMORIES OF
THEIR LOVED ONES.
THOSE OF US FROM OUTSIDE ARE NOW
LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE WOMEN
AND THE CHILDREN WHO LOST THEIR
LIVES ON FRIDAY AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
TAKE A LOOK.
>> VICTORIA SOTO'S FAMILY SAYS
SHE HAD HER STUDENTS HUDDLED
BEHIND HER TRYING TO PROTECT
THEM WHEN SHE WAS SHOT AND
KILLED AT THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
HER COUSIN SAYS THE HARDEST PART
WAS WAITING TO HEAR WHETHER SHE
HAD SURVIVED OR NOT.
>> AT THAT POINT, IT WAS THE
HARDEST FOR THE WHOLE FAMILY,
JUST THE WAITING GAME.
TO RECEIVE WORD ON WHAT HAPPENED
TO VICKI'S CLASS.
>> ALSO KILLED, LAUREN RUSSO,
HIRED JUST LAST MONTH AS A
PERMANENT SUBSTITUTE TEACHER.
HER FAMILY SAYS SHE ALWAYS
WANTED TO BE A TEACHER SINCE
BEFORE SHE EVEN WENT TO
KINDERGARTEN.
THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST SAYS ON
HER WEB PAGE SHE HAS TWO
DAUGHTERS IN THEIR 20s, MARRIED
31 YEARS.
AND THE PRINCIPAL, DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG SAYING SHE WAS
EXCITED ABOUT TEACHING.
>> TO LOSE SOMEBODY LIKE THAT IN
OUR DISTRICT, IT'S SAD.
>> SHE WAS A PERSONAL FRIEND AND
A WONDERFUL LEADER.
>> SHE HAD RECENTLY OVERSEEN THE
INSTALLATION OF A NEW SECURITY
SYSTEM REQUIRING EVERY VISITOR
AFTER 9:30 A.M. TO GET BUZZED IN
AND SHOW ID.
>> SHE TRULY DID BELIEVE IN
CREATING AN ENVIRONMENT WHERE
CHILDREN FELT SAFE.
I THINK THAT THAT'S REALLY THE
TRAGIC IRONY OF THIS ENTIRE
SITUATION.
>> SHE WAS ALSO A PARENT
HERSELF, RAISING TWO DAUGHTERS
AND THREE STEPDAUGHTERS.
FRIENDS AND PARENTS SAY
HOCHSPRUNG WAS PASSIONATE AND
DEDICATED, TOUGH BUT CARING AND
ONE SAID THE KIDS LOVED HER.
>> THE PRINCIPAL WHO, GOD BLESS
HER, LOST HER LIFE, WAS JUST A
VERY SPECIAL PERSON AND ALL THE
PARENTS KNEW THAT.
>> WOLF BLITZER, CNN, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> AT ONE POINT EARLIER TONIGHT,
A MAN STEPPED FORWARD BEFORE
CAMERAS TO PAY AN INCREDIBLY
LOVING TRIBUTE TO HIS OWN
DAUGHTER, EMILIE PARKER WAS JUST
6 YEARS OLD.
SHE WAS ONE OF THE LITTLE GIRLS
KILLED YESTERDAY.
HER FATHER, ROBBIE PARKER, SAID
HE IS EVEN PRAYING FOR THE
SHOOTER'S FAMILY.
WATCH.
>> I'D REALLY LIKE TO OFFER OUR
DEEPEST CONDOLENCES TO THE
FAMILIES WHO WERE DIRECTLY
AFFECTED BY THIS SHOOTING.
IT'S AN HORRIFIC TRAGEDY AND WE
WANT EVERYBODY TO KNOW THAT OUR
HEARTS AND OUR PRAYERS GO OUT TO
THEM.
THIS INCLUDES THE FAMILY OF THE
SHOOTER.
I CAN'T IMAGINE HOW HARD THIS
EXPERIENCE MUST BE FOR YOU AND I
WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT OUR FAMILY
AND OUR LOVE AND OUR SUPPORT
GOES OUT TO YOU AS WELL.
MY DAUGHTER, EMILIE, WOULD BE
ONE OF THE FIRST ONES TO BE
STANDING AND GIVING HER LOVE AND
SUPPORT TO ALL THOSE VICTIMS
BECAUSE THAT'S THE TYPE OF
PERSON THAT SHE IS, NOT BECAUSE
OF ANY PARENTING THAT MY WIFE
AND I COULD HAVE DONE, BUT
BECAUSE THOSE WERE THE GIFTS
THAT WERE GIVEN TO HER BY HER
HEAVENLY FATHER.
I HAVE TWO REALLY GOOD FRIENDS
AT HOME WHO HAVE SET UP A
FACEBOOK PAGE TO HELP RAISE
MONEY FOR EMILIE.
WHEN I'VE GOTTEN ON THAT AND
SEEN THE NUMBER OF PEOPLE WHO
HAVE COMMENTED AND EXPRESSED
THEIR CONDOLENCES, IT'S BEEN
QUITE OVERWHELMING.
AS THE DEEP PAIN BEGINS TO
SETTLE INTO OUR HEARTS, WE FIND
COMFORT REFLECTING ON THE
INCREDIBLE PERSON THAT EMILIE
WAS AND HOW MANY LIVES THAT SHE
WAS ABLE TO TOUCH IN HER SHORT
TIME HERE ON EARTH.
EMILIE WAS BRIGHT, CREATIVE AND
VERY LOVING.
EMILIE WAS ALWAYS WILLING TO TRY
NEW THINGS, OTHER THAN FOOD.
SHE LOVED TO USE HER TALENTS TO
TOUCH THE LIVES OF EVERYONE THAT
SHE CAME INTO CONTACT WITH.
SHE WAS AN EXCEPTIONAL ARTIST
AND SHE ALWAYS CARRIED AROUND
HER MARKERS AND PENCILS SO SHE
NEVER MISSED AN OPPORTUNITY TO
DRAW A PICTURE OR MAKE A CARD
FOR THOSE AROUND HER.
I CAN'T COUNT THE NUMBER OF
TIMES EMILIE NOTICED SOMEONE
FEELING SAD OR FRUSTRATED AND
WOULD RUSH TO FIND A PIECE OF
PAPER TO DRAW THEM A PICTURE OR
TO WRITE THEM AN ENCOURAGING
NOTE.
EMILIE'S CARD MAKING WAS
EXPRESSED BEAUTIFULLY THIS LAST
OCTOBER WHEN SHE PLACED A VERY
SPECIAL CARD SHE HAD MADE INTO
THE CASKET WITH HER GRANDPA, WHO
ALSO JUST RECENTLY DIED OF A
TRAGIC ACCIDENT.
EMILIE WAS A MENTOR TO HER TWO
LITTLE SISTERS AND DELIGHTED IN
TEACHING THEM HOW TO READ, DANCE
AND FIND THE SIMPLE JOYS IN
LIFE.
EMILIE'S LAUGHTER WAS INFECTIOUS
AND ALL THOSE WHO HAD THE
PLEASURE TO MEET HER WOULD AGREE
THAT THIS WORLD IS A BETTER
PLACE BECAUSE SHE'S BEEN IN IT.
SHE WAS THEIR BEST FRIEND.
THEY WERE ALL BORN WITHIN THREE
YEARS OF EACH OTHER SO BY LAW,
THEY'RE VERY CLOSE.
SHE WAS TEACHING MY MIDDLE
DAUGHTER TO READ.
SHE WOULD HELP MY YOUNGEST
DAUGHTER LEARN HOW TO MAKE
THINGS, SHOW HER HOW TO DO
CRAFTS.
THEY LOOKED UP TO HER AND THEY
LOOKED TO HER WHEN THEY NEEDED
COMFORT.
USUALLY THAT'S SAVED FOR A MOM
AND A DAD.
BUT IT WAS REALLY SWEET TO SEE
THE TIMES WHEN ONE OF THEM WOULD
FALL OR GET THEIR FEELINGS HURT,
HOW THEY WOULD RUN TO EMILIE TO
GET SUPPORT AND HUGS AND KISSES.
SHE WAS THE TYPE OF PERSON THAT
COULD JUST LIGHT UP A ROOM.
SHE ALWAYS HAD SOMETHING KIND TO
SAY ABOUT ANYBODY.
AND HER LOVE AND THE STRENGTH
THAT SHE GAVE US AND THE EXAMPLE
THAT SHE SHOWED TO US IS
REMARKABLE.
SHE IS AN INCREDIBLE PERSON.
AND I'M SO BLESSED TO BE HER
DAD.
I WAS LEAVING TO WORK AND SHE
WOKE UP BEFORE I LEFT.
AND I'VE ACTUALLY BEEN TEACHING
HER PORTUGUESE.
SO OUR LAST CONVERSATION WAS IN
PORTUGUESE.
AND SHE TOLD ME GOOD MORNING.
ASKED HOW I WAS DOING.
I SAID THAT I WAS DOING WELL.
SHE SAID THAT SHE LOVED ME.
I GAVE HER A KISS AND I WAS OUT
THE DOOR.
FREE AGENCY IS GIVEN TO ALL OF
US TO ACT AND DO WHAT WE WANT.
GOD CAN'T TAKE THAT AWAY FROM
US.
I KNOW THAT THAT'S SOMETHING
THAT HE WAS GIVEN AND THAT'S
WHAT HE CHOSE TO DO WITH IT.
I KNOW THAT GOD CAN'T TAKE THAT
AWAY.
I'M NOT MAD BECAUSE I HAVE MY
AGENCY TO MAKE SURE THAT I USE
THIS EVENT TO DO WHAT I CAN TO
DO WHATEVER I CAN.
TO WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT MY
FAMILY AND MY WIFE AND MY
DAUGHTERS ARE TAKEN CARE OF AND
THAT IF THERE'S ANYTHING THAT I
CAN DO TO HELP ANYBODY AT ANY
TIME, ANYWHERE, I'D BE WILLING
TO DO THAT.
AS WE MOVE ON FROM WHAT HAPPENED
HERE, WHAT HAPPENED TO SO MANY
PEOPLE, LET IT NOT TURN INTO
SOMETHING THAT DEFINES US, BUT
SOMETHING THAT INSPIRES US TO BE
BETTER, TO BE MORE COMPASSIONATE
AND MORE HUMBLE PEOPLE.
>> A FATHER IN MOURNING SPEAKING
OF COMPASSION FOR OTHERS.
WHAT HAPPENED AT THAT SCHOOL IS
SADLY JUST THE LATEST ON A LONG
LIST OF VIOLENT ATTACKS WITH
GUNS OVER THE YEARS.
WHEN WE FIRST HEARD WHAT
HAPPENED IN CONNECTICUT, PEOPLE
PROBABLY THOUGHT ABOUT THE OTHER
DEADLY SHOOTINGS.
JOINING ME NOW IS PASTOR ROCKY
VEACH WHO WAS LIVING NEAR
LITTLETON, COLORADO, WHEN THE
COLUMBINE ATTACK OCCURRED.
WHAT DO YOU SAY FOR FAMILIES WHO
COME TO YOU AND PEOPLE IN THIS
COMMUNITY WHO WEREN'T EVEN
HAVING A LOVED ONE AT THAT
SCHOOL BUT WHO JUST -- EVERYBODY
FEELS AFFECTED.
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
>> YEAH, AS A CHRISTIAN, WHAT
CAN YOU SAY TO START WITH?
BUT AS A CHRISTIAN, YOU TELL
THEM, THERE'S HOPE IN THE LORD.
GOD KNOWS WHERE YOU'RE AT.
GOD CARES FOR YOU AND LOVES YOU.
RATHER THAN SAYING A LOT ABOUT
JESUS, TRYING TO BE LIKE JESUS.
>> IT SEEMS, TOO, A LOT OF TIMES
JUST BEING THERE IS IMPORTANT
AND LISTENING IS AS IMPORTANT AS
WHAT YOU SAY.
>> YEAH, VERY MUCH SO.
THAT'S WHAT ANYBODY NEEDS IN
THIS KIND OF SETTING.
AND HAVING BEEN IN THIS SETTING
A TIME BEFORE, AND ACTUALLY I'M
GLAD TO BE AROUND TO BE ABLE TO
HELP PEOPLE HERE.
>> YOU FEEL LIKE YOU'RE IN THE
RIGHT PLACE AT THE RIGHT TIME.
>> YEAH, RIGHT PLACE AT THE
RIGHT TIME.
AND THE CHURCH THAT I PASTOR, I
THINK THEY FEEL THAT WAY, TOO.
WE'VE BEEN CONDUCTING PRAYER
MEETINGS IN THE AREA, PRAYING
FOR PEOPLE.
AND GETTING IN TOUCH WITH GOD
AND ASKING HIM TO HELP THEM AND
HELP USE US IN WAYS THAT CAN BE
HELPFUL TOWARD OTHER PEOPLE.
>> IT IS EXTRAORDINARY -- I'VE
SPENT A LITTLE BIT OF TIME IN
THIS TOWN.
JUST TO SEE HOW PEOPLE ARE
COMING TOGETHER.
PEOPLE ARE STOPPING HERE, PEOPLE
ARE STOPPING DOWN THE STREET AND
JUST KIND OF TALKING TO ONE
ANOTHER, COMPLETE STRANGERS KIND
OF REACHING OUT TO ONE ANOTHER
IN GRIEF AND IN SADNESS.
>> YEAH, I THINK IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
I THINK IT'S SOMETHING IN ALL OF
US THAT CAN HELP ALLEVIATE THE
PAIN WHEN WE GO THROUGH A CRISIS
SITUATION.
WE NEED EACH OTHER AND THAT'S
ONE OF THE BEAUTIFUL THINGS
ABOUT COMMUNITY.
>> DO YOU ENCOURAGE PEOPLE TO
TALK ABOUT IT?
I LOST A BROTHER YEARS AGO TO
SUICIDE.
AND MY MOM FOUND IT HELPFUL TO
TALK ABOUT IT OVER AND OVER
AGAIN.
AND I FOUND IT VERY, VERY
DIFFICULT AND EVEN STILL TO THIS
DAY.
DO YOU ENCOURAGE PEOPLE TO TALK?
>> I ENCOURAGE PEOPLE TO TALK
ABOUT IT.
AND I ENCOURAGE PEOPLE TO TALK
TO THE LORD ABOUT IT.
SOMETIMES WE FORGET THAT WE CAN
TALK TO GOD, TALK TO HIM
DIRECTLY.
AND HE UNDERSTANDS IN A WAY THAT
A PERSON REALLY CAN'T.
AGAIN, EVERYTHING I'M ABOUT IS
LOOKING TO HIM.
>> THERE ARE NO DOUBT PEOPLE WHO
WITNESS WHAT HAPPENED AND
QUESTION FAITH, QUESTION HOW CAN
THIS HAPPEN -- HOW CAN THIS BE
ALLOWED TO HAPPEN?
HOW DO YOU ANSWER?
>> THAT'S THE AGE-OLD QUESTION.
I LOOK AT EVIL -- TO BELIEVE IN
EVIL, YOU HAVE TO BELIEVE IN
GOOD.
I GO BACK TO THE STORY OF
CREATION.
GOD'S THE CREATOR AND THERE IS
AN ADVERSARY, THERE IS AN ENEMY.
GOD'S NOT THE AUTHOR OF THIS.
THE BIBLE SAYS THAT GOD IS THE
AUTHOR OF ABUNDANT LIFE.
THE DEVIL IS THE AUTHOR OF THIS
KIND OF LIFE.
HE COMES TO STEAL, KILL AND
DESTROY.
IT'S SAD.
BUT GOD IS BIGGER THAN THAT.
THAT'S WHY WE POINT PEOPLE
TOWARDS HIM IN THIS KIND OF
SCENARIO.
>> AND FAITH GETS YOU THROUGH?
>> FAITH GETS YOU THROUGH.
I THINK PEOPLE FIND THAT FAITH
GETS THEM THROUGH A LOT OF
THINGS THAT YOU MIGHT NOT THINK
IT WILL AT THE TIME.
HAVING LIVED IN COLUMBINE, I SAW
THIS ONCE BEFORE -- OR IN DENVER
DURING COLUMBINE, SAW THIS ONCE
BEFORE.
IT'S AMAZING.
CHANGED MY LIFE WATCHING HOW
OTHER PEOPLE -- HOW GOD DID HELP
THEM AND DID GET THEM THROUGH
TIMES WHEN THEY THOUGHT THEY
WOULDN'T MAKE IT THROUGH.
>> AND TO SEE PARENTS -- TO SEE
MR. PARKER SPEAKING ABOUT HIS
DAUGHTER, THE STRENGTH THAT
TAKES, THE STRENGTH THAT TAKES
JUST TO GET THROUGH MINUTE BY
MINUTE, SECOND BY SECOND.
>> YEAH.
NO, THAT WAS VERY TOUCHING
THERE.
IT'S JUST A HORRIBLE SCENARIO, A
HORRIBLE SITUATION.
LIKE WE SAID IN THE BEGINNING,
WORDS CAN'T REALLY DO ANYTHING
IN THIS.
HOW CAN I UNDERSTAND HIM?
I JUST TRY TO LOVE HIM AND BE
THERE FOR HIM AND PEOPLE LIKE
HIM, BE THERE IN THE COMMUNITY.
>> SOMETIMES THE WORDS SEEM --
THEY FEEL SO SMALL IN A
SITUATION LIKE THIS.
PASTOR, APPRECIATE YOU BEING ON.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> THERE'S STILL A LOT FOR US TO
LEARN IN THE DAYS AHEAD AND AS
OUR COVERAGE CONTINUES.
WE'LL TAKE A SHORT BREAK.
WE'LL CONTINUE REMEMBERING THE
VICTIMS TONIGHT WHEN WE COME
BACK.
>>> THIS IS A VERY, VERY TRAGIC,
TRAGIC SCENE FOR EVERYBODY.
CERTAINLY OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN
FOR THE FAMILIES HERE.
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, ABOUT 9:30,
9:40, WE HEARD NOISES.
AND THE ANNOUNCEMENT SYSTEM WAS
STILL ON.
SO IT DIDN'T GO OFF.
SO YOU COULD HEAR WHAT SOUNDED
LIKE POPS, GUNSHOTS.
>> HER TEACHER MANAGED TO TAKE
TWO CHILDREN OUT OF THE HALLWAY,
PULL THEM INTO THE CLASSROOM,
LOCK THE DOOR AND MOVE EVERYBODY
OVER TO THE OTHER SIDE OF THE
ROOM.
>> WE JUST TOLD A LITTLE BOY
ABOUT HIS SISTER NOW.
HE SAID, WHO AM I GOING TO PLAY
WITH NOW?
I HAVE NOBODY TO PLAY WITH NOW.
EXCUSE ME.
>> WHEN YOUR FIRST-GRADER GOES
TO BED AND SAYS, MOMMY, IS
ANYONE FROM MY CLASS LAST
YEAR -- ARE THEY ALL OKAY?
AND YOU LOOK AT THEM AND SAY,
I'M NOT REALLY SURE.
>> YOU CAN NEVER BE PREPARED FOR
THIS KIND OF INCIDENT.
WHAT HAS HAPPENED, WHAT HAS
TRANSPIRED AT THAT SCHOOL
BUILDING WILL LEAVE A MARK ON
THIS COMMUNITY AND EVERY FAMILY
IMPACTED.
>> AS I'VE BEEN SAYING SINCE THE
BEGINNING OF OUR COVERAGE, WE
WANT TO REALLY FOCUS ON THE
VICTIMS, ON THE LIVES THEY
LIVED.
AND WE WANT TODAY TO TRY TO
LEARN AS MUCH AS WE CAN ABOUT
THEM AND IN THE DAYS AHEAD, TO
THEM AS WHEN THEIR FAMILIES WANT
THAT INFORMATION OUT.
AT THIS POINT, WE DON'T HAVE
PICTURES OF MANY OF THE VICTIMS.
WE'RE WAITING OF COURSE FOR
FAMILIES TO RELEASE THAT IF AND
WHEN THEY CHOOSE TO.
BUT WE DO HAVE THEIR NAMES
TONIGHT.
AND I JUST WANT TO TAKE A FEW
MOMENTS AND JUST READ YOU THEIR
NAMES SO THAT YOU REMEMBER THEIR
NAMES.
SO OFTEN WE REMEMBER THE NAMES
OF THE SHOOTERS IN THESE KIND OF
SITUATIONS.
I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT TO
REMEMBER THE NAMES OF THE
VICTIMS INSTEAD.
CHARLOTTE BACON WAS JUST 6 YEARS
OLD.
WE REMEMBER HER TONIGHT.
DANIEL BARDEN WAS 7 YEARS OLD.
WE REMEMBER HIM TONIGHT.
RACHEL DAVINO, TEACHER, WAS 29
YEARS OLD.
WE REMEMBER HER.
OLIVIA ENGEL, 6 YEARS OLD.
OUR THOUGHTS ARE WITH HER
FAMILY.
JOSEPHINE GAY WAS 7 YEARS OLD.
SHE JUST HAD A BIRTHDAY ON
TUESDAY.
ANA MARQUEZ-GREENE WAS 6 YEARS
OLD.
DYLAN HOCKLEY, 6 YEARS OLD.
PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG 47
YEARS OLD.
MADELEINE WAS 6 YEARS OLD.
CATHERINE HUBBARD WAS 6 YEARS
OLD AS WELL.
CHASE KOWALSKI WAS 6 YEARS OLD.
JESSE LEWIS.
JAMES WAS 6 YEARS OLD AS WELL.
GRACE McDONNELL, 7 YEARS OLD.
ANNE MARIE MURPHY, SHE WAS A
TEACHER, 52 YEARS OLD.
EMILIE PARKER, SHE WAS 6 YEARS
OLD.
JACK PINTO, ALSO 6.
NOAH POZNER WAS 6 YEARS OLD.
CAROLINE PREVIDI WAS 6 YEARS OLD
AS WELL.
JESSICA WAS 6.
AVIELLE RICHMAN WAS ALSO 6.
SHE WAS KILLED YESTERDAY.
LAUREN WAS A SUBSTITUTE TEACHER,
30 YEARS OLD.
MARY SHERLACH, THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST, SHE WAS 56.
TEACHER VICTORIA SOTO WAS 27.
BENJAMIN WHEELER WAS 6 YEARS
OLD.
AND ALLISON WYATT WAS 6 YES
OLD AS WELL.
WE REMEMBER THEM ALL TONIGHT AND
IN THE DAYS, THE WEEKS AND
HOPEFULLY THE YEARS AHEAD.
A VIGIL IN MAIN STREET HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A SHORT
BREAK AND BE BACK IN A MOMENT.
>>> THE SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN IS
NOW IF SECOND DEADLIEST SCHOOL
SHOOTING IN U.S. HISTORY BEHIND
THE VIRGINIA TECH MASSACRE IN
2007.
AFTER EVERY EVENT LIKE THIS, THE
QUESTIONS ALWAYS ARE THE SAME,
WHAT CAUSES THIS KIND OF A
SHOOTING?
HOW CAN THIS HAPPEN?
HOW CAN THEY BE STOPPED?
I'M JOINED NOW BY KATHERINE
NEWMAN FROM BALTIMORE WHO WROTE
THE BOOK "RAMPAGE, THE SOCIAL
ROOTS OF SCHOOL SHOOTINGS" SHE'S
STUDIED MANY OF THESE KINDS OF
EVENTS.
I'VE READ A LITTLE BIT ABOUT
YOUR RESEARCH.
WHAT HAVE YOU LEARNED ABOUT
THESE SHOOTINGS THAT ARE SORT OF
COUNTERINTUITIVE?
PEOPLE THINK THEY KNOW WHAT
CAUSES THEM AT TIMES ABOUT THE
COLUMBINE.
BUT SO MANY OF THE THINGS WE
THOUGHT WE KNEW ABOUT COLUMBINE
HAVE TURNED OUT NOT TO BE TRUE.
WHAT DO WE NOW KNOW ABOUT WHAT
CAUSES THESE KINDS OF EVENTS?
>> THAT'S SO TRUE.
SOME OF THE COMMON MYTHS ARE
THAT THESE THINGS ARE
SPONTANEOUS.
THEY'RE ALMOST NEVER
SOME OF THE SHOOTINGS WE STUDIED
WERE PLANNED OVER A NINE-MONTH
PERIOD.
SADLY IN MANY INSTANCES, THERE
ARE QUITE A FEW PEOPLE WHO HAVE
AN INKLING.
IN SOME OF THE SCHOOL SHOOTINGS
WE STUDIED, THERE WERE CHILDREN
WHO DIDN'T COME TO SCHOOL THAT
DAY BECAUSE THEY WERE WORRIED
SOMETHING WAS GOING TO HAPPEN
BUT SADLY THEY NEVER TOLD ANYONE
WHO COULD HAVE DONE ANYTHING.
AND SO ONE OF THE
COUNTERINTUITIVE THINGS WE
LEARNED WAS THAT THERE'S A LOT
OF INFORMATION OFTEN CIRCULATING
BUT IT DOESN'T GET TO THE RIGHT
PLACE.
IT DOESN'T MEAN THAT WAS TRUE IN
THIS PARTICULAR INSTANCE.
IT WILL TAKE TIME BEFORE WE KNOW
ENOUGH TO GENERALIZE TO IT.
BUT IN THE STUDIES WE STUDIED --
AND WE STUDIED ALL OF THEM FROM
THE 1970s ONWARD IN THE UNITED
STATES, IT WAS FREQUENTLY THE
CASE THAT THERE WAS A LOT OF
KNOWLEDGE IN PEER COMMUNITIES
THAT DIDN'T GET THROUGH TO THE
ADULTS IN TIME TO DO ANYTHING
ABOUT IT.
IT'S ALSO THE CASE THAT IT
FREQUENTLY HAPPENS IN TOWNS JUST
LIKE NEWTOWN, SMALL, RURAL
SETTINGS, NOT THE PLACES THAT WE
THINK OF AS CHARACTERISTICALLY
VIOLENT.
WE THINK OF BIG CITIES AS PLACES
WHERE THERE'S GUN VIOLENCE.
AND OF COURSE THERE IS.
BUT THESE KINDS OF SHOOTINGS
DON'T HAPPEN IN BIG CITIES.
THEY HAPPEN USUALLY IN SMALL
TOWNS OR SUBURBS.
>> AND IS THERE A COMMON THREAD
IN THE MENTAL HEALTH HISTORY OF
THE BOYS INVOLVED IN THESE?
>> THERE IS ALMOST ALWAYS A
MENTAL HEALTH CONDITION.
THE SAD THING IS IT'S OFTEN
UNRECOGNIZED AND UNTREATED.
SO WE DON'T KNOW IF THAT WILL BE
TRUE IN THIS CASE.
BUT IN MOST OF THE CASES WE
LOOKED AT, THERE WAS
AFTER-THE-FACT EVIDENCE OF
MENTAL DISORDERS BUT NO
TREATMENT.
THAT'S DISTURBING BECAUSE WE
LIKE TO THINK WE CAN RECOGNIZE
THE SYMPTOMS.
BUT PARTICULARLY WHEN THE
SHOOTERS ARE YOUNGER THAN THIS
ONE, THE ONES WE LOOKED AT WERE
13, 12, THE SIGNS OF
DISTINGUISHED MENTAL ILLNESS
THAT ARE GOING TO BE SO VIVID IF
THEY SURVIVE INTO THEIR 20s ARE
NOT SO EASY TO DISCERN WHEN
THEY'RE 13.
SO SADLY THERE IS A -- THERE'S
EVIDENCE AFTER THE FACT OFTEN
THAT COMES UP IN FORENSIC
EXAMINATIONS, BUT NOT THE KIND
OF EVIDENCE THAT LEADS TO THE
TREATMENT THAT THEY SO
DESPERATELY NEED.
>> IT'S ALSO INTERESTING IN THE
BOOK TITLE, YOU TALK ABOUT THE
SOCIAL ROOTS OF THESE SHOOTINGS.
OFTENTIMES THE IDEAS THAT THESE
ARE LONERS ON THE FRINGE.
BUT YOU'VE FOUND IT'S NOT THAT
SIMPLE.
>> NO.
SADLY THEY ARE RARELY LONERS.
IT'S MORE CHARACTERISTIC TO SAY
THEY'RE FAILED JOINERS.
THEY ARE PEOPLE WHO HAVE
TYPICALLY TRIED TO JOIN GROUPS
AND ARE REBUFFED AND REJECTED.
SO THEIR EXPERIENCE IS NOT THAT
OF BEING A LONER.
IT'S OF BEING PUSHED ASIDE AND
MADE TO FEEL REJECTED.
AND SO WHAT TYPICALLY HAPPENS
WITH THESE YOUNG MEN IS THAT
THEY GO THROUGH A WHOLE SERIES
OF EFFORTS TO TRY AND GET
ATTENTION AND INGRATIATE
THEMSELVES IN GROUPS.
ALL THOSE EFFORTS FAIL AND THEY
START TALKING ABOUT SHOOTING
PEOPLE AND SUDDENLY EVERYONE'S
PAYING ATTENTION.
SO THEY'RE TRYING TO CHANGE HOW
PEOPLE THINK ABOUT THEM AND
NOTORIOUS AND EVIL SEEMS BETTER
TO THEM THAN A LOSER.
>> IT'S ONE OF THE REASONS I
BELIEVE JUST IN NOT TRYING TO
MENTION THEIR NAMES BECAUSE JUST
THE IDEA THAT SOMEBODY CAN
BELIEVE THAT THEY CAN GAME FAME
OR NOTORIETY BY DOING THIS, I
JUST DON'T THINK IT'S GOOD TO
PERPETUATE THAT.
I FIND YOUR RESEARCH REALLY
FASCINATING.
I'D LOVE TO TALK TO YOU MORE IN
THE DAYS AHEAD.
THANKS FOR BEING WITH US.
>> MY PLEASURE, ANDERSON.
>> SOME MEMORIES ARE SEARED INTO
OUR MINDS NO MATTER HOW MUCH ONE
WANTS TO FORGET THEM.
THE NEWTOWN SHOOTING NO DOUBT
FALLS INTO THAT CATEGORY FOR ONE
OF THE SCHOOL'S TEACHERS.
YET IN THE MIDST OF A CRISIS,
SHE STAYED REMARKABLY CALM FOR
HER KINDERGARTEN STUDENTS.
I TALKED TO HER, JANET VOLLMER
IS HER NAME.
I WANT YOU TO HEAR WHAT SHE SAID
ABOUT HOW SHE GOT HERSELF
THROUGH THIS CRISIS.
LISTEN.
>> ABOUT 9:30, 9:40, WE HEARD
NOISES.
AND THE ANNOUNCEMENT SYSTEM WAS
STILL ON.
SO IT DIDN'T GO OFF.
SO YOU COULD HEAR WHAT SOUNDED
LIKE POPS, GUNSHOTS.
OF COURSE I'M NOT GOING TO TELL
THAT TO 5-YEAR-OLDS.
SO I SAID TO THEM, WE'RE GOING
OVER IN A SAFE AREA AND WE'RE
GOING TO -- WE READ A STORY AND
WE KEPT THEM CALM.
DID A LOCKDOWN DRILL, CLOSED THE
DOORS, LOCKED -- COVERED THE
WINDOWS.
KEPT THE CHILDREN WITH US.
I HAVE OTHER ADULTS --
>> I FIND THAT AMAZING THAT
FEARING THAT YOU HEAR GUNSHOTS,
YOU WERE ABLE TO HAVE THE
COMPOSURE TO SIT DOWN AND READ
TO YOUR STUDENTS.
THAT'S EXTRAORDINARY.
>> THAT'S WHAT YOU HAVE TO DO
WITH 5-YEAR-OLDS BECAUSE YOU
CAN'T LOSE IT.
I'VE BEEN DOING THIS FOR A LONG
TIME.
IT'S MY 18th YEAR OF TEACHING.
MY JOB WAS TO KEEP THEM SAFE.
I DIDN'T KNOW -- THERE WAS NO
ANNOUNCEMENT OF WHAT WAS GOING
ON.
MY INSTINCT WAS IT WASN'T GOOD.
SO WE KEPT THEM CALM.
WE STAYED IN THE ROOM UNTIL
THERE WAS BANGING AT THE DOOR,
WHICH WERE THE POLICE AND THE
TROOPERS OR WHOEVER WAS THERE.
THEY HAD US EXIT THE BUILDING.
THEY TOLD THE CHILDREN TO COVER
THEIR EYES AND WALK IN A LINE
AND LEAVE THE BUILDING AND
THAT'S WHEN WE WENT DOWN TOWARDS
THE FIREHOUSE.
WE WERE ALL SAFE.
I HAD 19 CHILDREN IN THE ROOM
WITH ME AND THANK GOODNESS ALL
OF THEIR PARENTS WERE ABLE TO
COME AND PICK THEM UP AND TAKE
THEM HOME.
>> AS YOU WERE READING TO THEM,
DID THE KIDS REALIZE SOMETHING
WAS GOING ON OR DID THEY JUST
THINK IT WAS A DRILL LIKE YOU'D
HAD BEFORE?
>> RIGHT.
IT DIDN'T SEEM A NATURAL THING.
ALTHOUGH WE DO PRACTICE DRILLS.
WE JUST SAID, WELL, WE'RE NOT
REALLY SURE BUT WE'RE GOING TO
BE SAFE BECAUSE WE'RE SITTING
OVER HERE AND WE'RE ALL
TOGETHER.
AND THAT'S AS WE GOT DOWN TO THE
FIREHOUSE LATER ON, AS A LOT OF
THE EVENTS STARTED TO UNFOLD
THROUGHOUT THE DAY, I THINK SOME
OF THEM REALIZED THE MAGNITUDE
OF WHAT WAS GOING ON.
THEY SAW OTHER PEOPLE UPSET.
BUT WE JUST HELD THEM CLOSE
UNTIL THEIR PARENTS CAME AND WE
RELEASED THEM.
MY ROOM, MY CHILDREN WERE ALL
ACCOUNTED FOR AND SAFE IN MY
KINDERGARTEN CLASSROOM.
>> WE TALKED ABOUT SOME OF THE
KIDS DEALING WITH THE POTENTIAL
FOR PTSD.
ALSO FIRST RESPONDERS DEALING
WITH THE STRESS IN ALL OF THIS
AND WHAT THEY'VE HAD TO SEE.
TERRY LYLES DEALS WITH STRESS
AND CRISIS MANAGEMENT.
HE JOINS ME FROM MIAMI.
IT IS EASY TO FORGET THESE
SCENES ARE PROBABLY THE WORST
MANY OF THESE EMERGENCY WORKERS
HAVE EVER WITNESSED.
I CAN'T IMAGINE THE THINGS THEY
SAW IN THOSE SCHOOLS -- IN THAT
SCHOOL.
YOU HELP RESCUE WORKERS DEAL
WITH TRAGEDY FOLLOWING THE
SEPTEMBER 11th ATTACKS.
WHAT'S YOUR ADVICE?
HOW DO YOU HELP THEM?
>> WELL, ANDERSON, THANK YOU FOR
HAVING ME.
I THINK THE BIGGEST THING THAT
WE HAVE TO REMEMBER IS THAT THE
CLOSEST YOU ARE TO THE
EPICENTER, HEARING THE SHOTS,
SEEING THE VIOLENCE VISUALLY,
THE MORE YOU'RE GOING TO NEED TO
BE ABLE TO DEBRIEF.
AS I DEBRIEF SPECIAL FORCES
PEOPLE AND SOLDIERS, IT'S VERY
IMPORTANT THAT THESE CHILDREN,
THEIR PARENTS UNDERSTAND THAT
THERE'S LIFE AFTER TRAGEDY BUT
WE HAVE TO LISTEN TO THEIR
STORIES, WE HAVE TO HELP THEM
VENT AND RELEASE THAT
INFORMATION THAT THEY CAN
NORMALIZE AND GO BACK TO SOME
TYPE OF LIFE AS THEY KNEW IT
BEFORE THIS TRAGIC DAY.
>> WHAT KIND OF SYMPTOMS DO
PARENTS, DO FRIENDS OF PEOPLE
NEED TO LOOK OUT FOR?
>> WELL, TYPICALLY WITH
CHILDREN, IT'S ALL AGE
APPROPRIATENESS.
SO IT REALLY DEPENDS.
BUT USUALLY SLEEP CAN BE
DISRUPTED.
THERE CAN BE NIGHTMARES.
THERE COULD BE SUDDEN NOISES
THAT COULD STARTLE THEM.
MOODINESS THAT YOU'VE NOT SEEN
BEFORE, MAYBE A LOSS IN APPETITE
OR A LOSS OF INTEREST IN NORMAL
THINGS.
AND I THINK FOR PARENTS MAINLY,
WE'RE ALL JUST MORTIFIED BY THIS
EVENT.
AND I THINK AS PARENTS WE HAVE
TO MAKE SURE THAT WE'RE TALKING
TO OUR CHILDREN, REGARDLESS OF
WHERE WE ARE IN THE COUNTRY OR
AROUND THE WORLD, THAT WE CAN
LET OUR CHILDREN KNOW AND
SUPPORT THEM TO SAY, LISTEN,
IT'S OKAY, THIS DOESN'T HAPPEN
ON A REGULAR BASIS.
THIS WAS NOT A NORMAL SITUATION
AND WE HAVE TO SUPPORT THEM AND
CARE FOR THEM THAT THEY KNOW
THAT THEY'RE SECURED IN A NORMAL
WORLD THAT WE LIVE IN.
>> BUT TALKING ABOUT IT HELPS?
>> WELL, AGAIN, IT DEPENDS ON
THE AGE.
THE AGES OF THE KIDS THAT YOU
MENTIONED, I AGREE WITH YOU.
I THINK IT'S VERY DIFFICULT TO
BE ABLE TO EVEN NAME THE NAMES
AND THE AGES OF THESE CHILDREN.
IT'S HEARTBREAKING.
AND I THINK WHAT HE CAN DO, AS
WE TALK TO OUR CHILDREN, IF
CHILDREN CAN DRAW PICTURES AND
WRITE LETTERS IF THAT'S WHAT IT
GOES, TO FRIENDS THAT THEY LOST
OR THE SITUATIONS THEY HEARD AND
DESTROY THOSE LETTERS.
WE DESTROY EVERYTHING THAT IS OF
WASTE TO US.
WE PUT GARBAGE BAGS OUT.
WE FLUSH GARBAGE DISPOSALS.
IT'S THE SAME WAY WITH THE
EMOTIONAL WASTE.
WE HAVE TO HELP THEM VENT AND
PROCESS, RELEASE IT AND LET THEM
KNOW AS WE TALK TO THEM THAT
THEY HAVE A REFUGE WITHIN US AND
THAT WE AS PARENTS ARE THERE TO
SUPPORT THEM THROUGH THIS
SITUATION.
>> TERRY LYLES, I APPRECIATE
YOUR EXPERTISE.
NO DOUBT, WE'LL BE TALKING TO
YOU IN THE DAYS AHEAD AS WELL.
TH