HAVE TO START DOING THINGS IN
AMERICA.
>> LISTEN, THANK YOU ALL FOR
JOINING ME.
ALL IN YOUR OWN WAY HAVE BEEN
THROUGH HORROR STORIES OF YOUR
OWN.
IT IS TIME.
PRESIDENT OBAMA TALKED IN A
MOVING AND EMOTIONAL WAY.
IT'S TIME FOR ACTION.
TIME THAT AMERICA'S POLITICIANS
JUST DID SOMETHING.
STOP WORRYING ABOUT THE GUN
LOBBY WHO MAKE MILLIONS,
BILLIONS OUT OF THIS TRADE IN
WHAT OFTEN LEADS TO APPALLING
DEATH IT IS TIME FOR SOME MORAL
CONVICTION AND SOME MORAL
COURAGE.
STAY WITH CNN ALL WEEKEND LONG
FOR THE LATEST ON THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
RIGHT BACK ON SUNDAY NIGHT WITH
A SPECIAL EDITION OF "PIERS
MORGAN TONIGHT" "AC 360 STARTS
NOW."
>>> PIERS, THANKS VERY MUCH.
10:00 ON THE EAST COAST.
ONLY ONE STORY TONIGHT.
NEW DETAILS TO TELL YOU ABOUT.
WE WON'T PRETEND WE UNDERSTAND
IT ANY BETTER THAN WE DID RIGHT
AFTER IT HAPPENED.
IT IS A HORROR BEYOND WORDS.
AB ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, KIDS AS
YOUNG AS 5 YEARS OLD, SECOND
DEADLIEST SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
THIS COUNTRY.
20 CHILDREN KILLED, 7 ADULTS,
INCLUDING THE ADULT SHOOTER.
ABOUT 90 MINUTES' DRIVE FROM.
ALL OF THE LATEST INFORMATION
TONIGHT.
WE WON'T REPEAT THE SHOOTER'S
NAME OVER AND OVER AGAIN AS HAS
BEEN DONE THROUGHOUT THE DAY.
WE DON'T WANT HISTORY TO
REMEMBER THIS MURDERER.
WE WANT HISTORY TO REMEMBER THE
VICTIMS, THE TEACHERS, THE
CHILDREN, THOSE WHOSE LIVES HAVE
BEEN UNFAIRLY TAKEN.
WE HAVE A TEAM OF REPORTERS
WORKING, INCLUDING SOLEDAD
O'BRAYEN ON THE SCENE.
>> A VIGIL HELD TONIGHT.
THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN TRYING TO
COME TO GRIPS WITH WHAT HAS
HAPPENED.
JUST BEHIND US THIS MORNING.
RIGHT NOW, RIGHT NOW, THIS IS
STILL AN ACTIVE CRIME SCENE THAT
MEANS MANY OF THE BODIES ARE
LYING WHERE THEY FELL INSIDE THE
SCHOOL, INCLUDING THE BODY OF A
KILLER.
WE WANT TO AT LEAST TELL YOU HIS
NAME.
AND AS ANDERSON, WE WON'T BE
REPEATING IT MUCH TONIGHT AT
ALL.
20 YEARS OLD.
HIS MOTHER TAUGHT AT THE SCHOOL.
SHE WAS FOUND DEAD AT THE FAMILY
HOME.
UNCLEAR EXACTLY HOW SHE DIED OR
WHEN SHE DIED.
>> SOLEDAD, THE IDEA THAT THOSE
KIDS ARE STILL IN THE SCHOOL, I
MEAN, IT IS SUCH A HORRIFIC
IMAGE TO THINK ABOUT TONIGHT,
AND FOR THE PARENTS, NOT TO BE
ABLE TO SEE THEIR CHILDREN YET.
>> YEAH, THE POLICE SAY IT'S AN
ACTIVE CRIME SCENE AND THEY TOLD
US THEY THOUGHT BY SUNDAY, THEY
WOULD BE ABLE TO HAVE THE CRIME
SCENE PART OF IT AND THE
INVESTIGATION AT LEAST THAT
PORTION OF THE WRAPPED UP.
BUT NOW WE'RE GETTING TOLD THAT
ACTUALLY IT MIGHT BE EVEN AS
SOON AS TOMORROW MORNING.
BUT AS YOU CAN IMAGINE, KNOWING
YOUR CHILD HAS PERISHED INSIDE
THAT SCHOOL AND YOU CAN'T EVEN
GO AND GET THE BODY, IT WOULD BE
A HORRIFIC THING.
>> LET'S HOPE THE CHILDREN ARE
BROUGHT HOME SOON.
WE KNOW THAT THE MOTHER OF THE
SHOOTER, LEGALLY PURCHASED THE
WEAPONS THAT WERE USED.
RITA COSBY REPORTS THAT HE BROKE
HIS WAY THROUGH THE FRONT DOOR
INTO THE SCHOOL, TWO SEMI
AUTOMATIC HANDGUNS AND A
BUSHMASTER.
POLICE IN HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY,
TOOK THE OLDER BROTHER IN FOR
QUESTIONING, DID NOT LABEL HIM A
SUSPECT.
NO WORD WHETHER HE'S STILL IN
CUSTODY.
A LOT TO TELL YOU ABOUT RIGHT
NOW THIS HOUR.
LET'S START AT THE BEGINNING.
>> INDIVIDUAL I HAVE ON THE
PHONE IS CONTINUING TO HEAR WHAT
HE BELIEVES TO BE GUNFIRE.
>> Reporter: THE FIRST WORD WAS
CHILLING.
IT ONLY GOT WORSE.
>> THEY ARE REPORTING MULTIPLE
FATALITIES INVOLVING IN THE
SHOOTING AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
>> Reporter: WITH EACH NEW
REPORT, THE HORROR DEEPENED.
>> THE NUMBER OF DEAD CLOSER TO
30 THAN 20, AND MOST ARE
CHILDREN.
>> Reporter: EVERY DETAIL
BROUGHT MORE SADNESS.
EACH FRESH PIECE OF INFORMATION,
PART OF THE PICTURE.
A SCHOOL, KINDERGARTEN THROUGH
FOURTH GRADE.
A SANCTUARY SUPPOSED TO BE A
PLACE OF SAFETY, TORN APART.
>> SHE HEARD THE INTERCOM CAME
ON IN THE SCHOOL AND HEARD A
SCREAM AND HEARD A GUNSHOT --
TWO GUNSHOTS, AND THE SCHOOL
WENT INTO LOCKDOWN.
>> Reporter: A STUDENT, TEENAGE
BIG BROTHER DESCRIBED THE SOUND.
>> NEWTOWN POLICE, IMMEDIATELY
UPON ARRIVAL ENTERED THE SCHOOL
AND BEGAN A COMPLETE ACTIVE
SHOOTER SEARCH OF THE BUILDING.
>> Reporter: THEY ARRIVED TO
CARNAGE.
THE KILLER WAS DRESSED FOR
BATTLE IN BLACK FATIGUES AND
ARMED FOR MASS MURDER.
TWO PISTOLS AND A MILITARY STYLE
RIFLE.
IN PARTS OF THE SCHOOL, STUDENTS
WERE TOLD TO HIDE IN CORNERS.
TEACHERS RISKED THEIR OWN LIVES
TO PULL BOYS AND GIRLS TO
SAFETY.
>> SO GRATEFUL TO THE TEACHER
WHO SAVED HIM.
>> THE TEACHER SAVED HIS LIFE?
>> SHE DEFINITELY DID.
HE HAD BULLETS GOING BY HIM AND
SHE GRABBED HIM AND ANOTHER
CHILD AND PULLED THEM INTO A
CLASSROOM.
>> EVENTUALLY, KIDS WERE
EVACUATED TO A NEARBY FIREHOUSE,
FROM FRANTIC PARENTS DESCENDED.
>> IT WAS TERRIFYING.
I'M STILL TERRIFIED AND STILL IN
SHOCK ABOUT IT ALL.
I DON'T KNOW EVERYTHING THAT
HAPPENED.
I KNOW THAT THERE ARE SOME
PEOPLE MISSING, TAKEN TO THE
HOSPITAL.
>> Reporter: HIS SON WAS OKAY.
HIS SON'S TEACHER WAS ALIVE AS
WELL.
20 OTHER CHILDREN AND 6 ADULTS
WERE KILLED.
THE DEAD BELIEVED TO INCLUDE
SANDY HOOK'S SCHOOL SKOEGS APSYT
AND THE PRINCIPAL.
THE GUNMAN'S MOTHER WAS
DISCOVERED REPORTEDLY AT HOME IN
NEWTO
NEWTOWN.
THE GUNMAN HIMSELF IS DEAD.
A TIGHT-KNIT COMMUNITY, A NURSE
RUSHED TO HELP, SHOT,
DISTRAUGHT.
>> I SEE HAVE YOU BEEN CRYING?
>> YES.
>> Reporter: BECAUSE OF WHAT YOU
SAW?
>> ONE OF THE COPS SAID IT'S THE
WORST THING HE HAD EVER SEEN IN
HIS ENTIRE CAREER, BUT IT WAS
WHEN THEY TOLD THE PATIENTS.
ALL OF THE PARENTS WAITING FOR
THE CHILDREN TO COME OUT.
THOUGHT THEY WERE STILL ALIVE.
THERE'S 20 PARENTS JUST TOLD
THAT THEIR CHILDREN ARE DEAD.
IT WAS AWFUL.
>> Reporter: AWFUL.
AND LATE TODAY, SPEAKING FOR THE
NATION, BUT ALSO AS A FATHER, AN
EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT OBAMA FOUGHT
BACK TEARS.
>> Reporter: THIS EVENING,
MICHELLE AND I WILL DO WHAT
EVERY PARENT IN AMERICA WILL DO,
WHICH IS HUG OUR CHILDREN A
LITTLE TIGHTER.
AND WE'LL TELL THEM THAT WE LOVE
THEM AND WE'LL REMIND EACH OTHER
HOW DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT.
AND THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT
NOW.
>> WE'LL PLAY YOU THE COMPLETE
STATEMENT THAT PRESIDENT OBAMA
MADE TODAY, WITH THE HOPE IT MAY
BRING SOME PEACE TO SOME PEOPLE.
AS ONE MOTHER SAID TONIGHT, TOO
MANY OF OUR BABIES DIED.
WITH US NOW, JANET VOLMER WHO
TEACHES KINDERGARTEN AT SANDY
HOOK AND WAS THERE TODAY.
FIRST OF ALL, HOW ARE YOU DOING?
>> I'M OKAY.
FAMILY IS HERE, THAT HELPS.
MY SONS CAME AND MY HUSBAND AND
THE DOG, SO WE'RE TOGETHER.
THAT'S WHAT IT'S ALL ABOUT.
IT WAS AWFUL.
>> YOU WERE IN YOUR CLASSROOM.
>> I WAS IN MY CLASSROOM.
WHAT DID YOU HEAR?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, ABOUT 9:30,
9:40, WE HEARD NOISES AND THE
ANNOUNCEMENT SYSTEM WAS STILL
ON, SO IT DIDN'T GO OFF, SO YOU
COULD HEAR WHAT SOUNDED LIKE
POPS, GUNSHOTS, OF COURSE, I'M
NOT GOING TO TELL THAT TO 5 YEAR
OLDS, AND I SAID WE'RE GOING
OVER IN A SAFE AREA AND WE'RE
GOING TO -- WE READ A STORY AND
KEPT THEM CALM.
DID A LOCKDOWN DRILL.
CLOSED THE DOOR, LOCKED, COVERED
THE WINDOWS.
AND, YOU KNOW, KEPT THE CHILDREN
WITH US.
I HAVE OTHER ADULTS --
>> I FIND THAT AMAZING -- I FIND
THAT AMAZING THAT FEARING THAT
YOU HEAR GUNSHOTS, YOU WERE ABLE
TO HAVE THE COMPOSURE TO SIT
DOWN AND READ TO YOUR STUDENTS.
THAT'S EXTRAORDINARY.
>> THAT'S WHAT YOU HAVE TO DO
WITH 5-YEAR-OLDS, YOU CAN'T LOSE
IT.
SO, YOU KNOW, YOU JUST KIND
OF -- I'VE BEEN DOING THIS FOR A
LONG TIME.
IT'S MY 18th YEAR OF TEACHING,
AND MY JOB WAS TO KEEP THEM
SAFE.
I DIDN'T KNOW -- NO ANNOUNCEMENT
OF WHAT WAS GOING ON.
YOU KNOW, MY I STINGT WAS IT
WASN'T GOOD.
SO WE KEPT THEM CALM, STAYED IN
THE ROOM UNTIL THERE WAS BANGING
AT THE DOOR, WHICH WAS POLICE,
TROOPERS, WHOEVER WAS THERE, AND
THEY HAD US EXIT THE BUILDING
AND TOLD THE CHILDREN TO COVER
THEIR EYES AND WALK IN A LINE
AND LEAVE THE BUILDING AND
THAT'S WHEN WE WENT DOWN TOWARD
THE FIREHOUSE.
SO, YOU KNOW, WE WERE ALL SAFE.
I HAD 19 CHILDREN IN THE ROOM
WITH ME, AND THANK GOODNESS,
THEIR PARENTS WERE ABLE TO COME,
PICK THEM UP, TAKE THEM HOME.
>> WHEN YOU WERE READING, DID
THE KIDS REALIZE SOMETHING WAS
GOING ON, OR THINK IT WAS A
DRILL LIKE BEFORE?
>> RIGHT, IT DIDN'T SEEM A
NATURAL THING, ALTHOUGH WE DO
PRACTICE DRILLS, AND WE JUST
SAID, WELL, WE'RE NOT REALLY
SURE, BUT WE'RE GOING TO BE
SAFE, BECAUSE WE'RE SITTING OVER
HERE AND WE'RE ALL TOGETHER.
AND THAT'S, YOU KNOW, AS WE GOT
DOWN TO THE FIREHOUSE, LATER ON,
THERE WAS A LOT OF THE EVENTS
STARTED TO UNFOLD THROUGHOUT THE
DAY, I THINK SOME OF THEM
REALIZED THE MAGNITUDE OF WHAT
WAS GOING ON, SAW OTHER PEOPLE
UPSET, BUT, YOU KNOW, WE JUST
HELD THEM CLOSE UNTIL THEIR
PARENTS CAME AND WE RELEASED
THEM, AND, YOU KNOW, MY ROOM, MY
CHILDREN, WERE ALL ACCOUNTED
FOR, AND SAFE IN MY KINDERGARTEN
CLASSROOM.
>> FOR ALL OF US,
INCOMPREHENSIBLE, YOU KNEW THE
CHILDREN, THE FAMILIES INVOLVED.
YOUR COLLEAGUES HAVE LOST THEIR
LIVES.
I CERTAINLY WON'T ASK YOU ABOUT
ANY OF THE KIDS.
WHAT DO YOU WANT THE WORLD TO
KNOW ABOUT YOUR COLLEAGUES?
>> YEAH, I MEAN, WE HEARD A LOT
OF THINGS AS WE WERE DOWN AT THE
FIREHOUSE.
YOU KNOW, PEOPLE WERE TEXTING
NEWS REPORTS AND THIS ONE, THAT
ONE, I'M SURE -- I'M NOT SURE
STILL OF THE MAGNITUDE OF WHO
EVERYONE IS, I HEAR SIX OR SEVEN
ADULTS AND MANY CHILDREN, AND,
YOU KNOW, I KNOW THOSE FIRST
GRADERS WERE CHILDREN I HAD IN
MY ROOM LAST YEAR.
SO THOSE PARENTS WERE SHOWING UP
TODAY, AND THEY COULDN'T FIND
THEIR CHILDREN, AND, YOU KNOW,
THEY WERE ALL TAKEN TO SEPARATE
ROOMS AND SO -- I DON'T KNOW WHO
THEY ALL ARE, BUT I'M SURE AS
THE DAYS UNFOLD, IT WILL NOT
BE -- IT WILL NOT BE GOOD NEWS
FOR MANY OF THOSE PEOPLE.
>> AND -- YEAH, IT'S REALLY
BEYOND WORDS, AND I APPRECIATE
YOU TAKING A FEW MOMENTS TO TALK
TO US TONIGHT.
IT REALLY IS --
>> WELL --
>> JANET, THANK YOU FOR YOUR
COMPOSURE.
>> YOU'RE WELCOME.
>> IT'S EXTRAORDINARY WHAT YOU
DID, AND THE OTHER COLLEAGUES OF
YOURS.
>> SOME OF THOSE TEACHERS WERE
HEROES.
ONE OF THE TEACHERS, SHE LOCKED
EVERYBODY IN THE BATHROOM.
AND WOULDN'T OPEN THE DOOR.
YOU KNOW, I THINK WE DO THIS AS
TEACHERS, WE ARE TRAINED, WE DO
HAVE DRILLS, WE TALK TO THE
KIDS, AND IN CASE SOMETHING WERE
TO HAPPEN, THIS IS WHAT WE DO.
AND IT'S KIND OF WHAT HAPPENED
TODAY.
EVERYBODY JUST IN STINCTIVELY
KEPT THE CHILDREN SAFE.
>> A LOT OF TEACHERS I THINK OF
HEROES, AND YOU AND YOUR
COLLEAGUES SHOWED THAT TODAY.
>> THANK YOU.
>> I WISH YOU PEACE AND STRENGTH
IN THE DIFFICULT DAYS AHEAD.
AMY RECEISEIVER IS JOINING US.
SHE IS A PARENT.
HOW IS YOUR DAUGHTER DOING, YOUR
FAMILY, HOW ARE YOU HOLDING UP?
>> OKAY.
IT'S A VERY ROUGH NIGHT HERE.
WHEN YOUR FIRST GRADER GOES TO
BED AND SAYS, MOMMY, IS ANYONE
FROM MY CLASS LAST YEAR, ARE
THEY ALL OKAY?
ARE THEY ALL OKAY?
AND YOU LOOK AT THEM AND SAY I'M
NOT REALLY SURE, IT'S NOT THE
BEST NIGHT WHEN YOU TELL THAT TO
YOUR 7-YEAR-OLD.
IT'S -- VERY, VERY SAD NIGHT FOR
THIS TOWN AND A LOT OF FAMILIES
HERE.
>> HAS YOUR DAUGHTER WANTED TO
TALK ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED OR
FIRST GRADE, I DON'T -- DO THEY
WANT TO TALK?
>> SHE ASKED A LOT OF QUESTIONS
ABOUT THE PRINCIPAL.
SHE CAUGHT WIND VERY QUICK THAT
WILL SOMETHING WAS WRONG WITH
OUR PRINCIPAL.
WHICH WE DIDN'T TELL HER UNTIL
JUST NOW THAT, YES, SHE WAS
DEFINITELY HURT AND IT WASN'T
GOOD.
IT TOOK HER -- IT'S TAKING HER A
WHILE.
I THINK TOMORROW WILL PROBABLY
BE HARDER FOR HER.
I ALSO HAVE A FIFTH GRADER WHO
CAME OFF THE BUS CRYING, BECAUSE
SHE, ONE, HAD A SISTER WHO SHE
WAS WORRIED ABOUT, AND JUST
BASICALLY LEFT THAT SCHOOL, A
FEW MONTHS AGO AND I THINK FOR A
LOT OF THOSE KIDS, THEY KIND OF
ARE A LITTLE OLDER AND CAN GET
IT A LITTLE BIT FASTER, EVEN
THOUGH THEY WEREN'T IN IT.
SO IT'S -- THE QUESTIONS I THINK
ARE COMING.
THEY ARE NOT REALLY HERE YET,
ESPECIALLY FOR THE LITTLER ONES,
BUT IT'S STARTED AS I PUT THEM
TO BED TONIGHT, THE QUESTIONS.
>> DO YOU KNOW -- AS A MOM, DO
YOU KNOW HOW YOU ARE GOING TO
ANSWER THOSE QUESTIONS?
BECAUSE THERE ARE A LOT OF
PARENTS AROUND THE WORLD,
FRANKLY, WHOSE KIDS ARE GOING TO
BE ASKING THEM QUESTIONS IN THE
DAYS AHEAD ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED.
DO YOU THINK YOU KNOW WHAT YOU
ARE GOING TO SAY?
>> UNFORTUNATELY, WE HAVE BEEN
THROUGH A BIT OF TRAUMA IN OUR
OWN LIFE, FOR ME, AND I CAN'T
SPEAK FOR MOMS -- OTHER MOMS OR
MOMS AROUND THE WORLD, BUT FOR
MY FAMILY, I SPEAK KIND OF
QUIETLY AND TRUSTFTHFULLY AND T
TO ANSWER THE QUESTIONS THAT
THEY ASK WITHOUT A LOT OF
DETAIL.
I DEFINITELY DON'T LIE.
IS PRINCE HOCHSPRUNG OKAY?
AND I SAID NO.
AND SHE SAID IS SHE DEAD?
AND I SAID YES.
I TRY NOT TO OFFER TOO MUCH.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THEY KNOW.
I SIT BACK AND WAIT FOR THEM TO
ASK.
IF THEY ASK, I GIVE THEM AN
HONEST ANSWER.
AND, UNFORTUNATELY, FOR A LOT OF
US IN TOWN, THE ANSWERS ARE NOT
GOOD.
>> THE PRINCIPAL, DAWN --
>> AND THEY ARE VERY SAD
TONIGHT, I DON'T THINK ANYONE
CAN ANSWER THESE QUESTIONS
EASILY -- THEY ARE DEFINITELY
NOT FUN ANSWERS.
>> I'VE HEARD SO MANY GREAT
THINGS ABOUT THE PRINCIPAL, DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG, AND THE FACT THAT
YOUR CHILD WAS ASKING ABOUT HER.
WHAT DO YOU WANT PEOPLE TO KNOW
ABOUT DAWN?
>> A VERY LOVELY COMPASSIONATE
WOMAN.
EXTREMELY HELPFUL.
AS A CHAIR ON ONE OF THE PTA
COMMITTEES, COULD NOT HAVE COME
OUT TO SUPPORT ME BETTER THIS
YEAR.
I NEEDED SUPPORT THIS YEAR, AND
SHE WAS THE FIRST ONE ON MY
TEAM, THE FIRST ONE TO HELP, THE
FIRST ONE TO BE THERE.
NEVER SAW HER WITHOUT A SMILE.
YOU KNOW, WAS JUST IN MY
DAUGHTER'S CLASSROOM THIS WEEK,
READING A BOOK TO THE KIDS.
VERY, VERY LOVELY, VERY LOVELY
WOMAN.
AND DEFINITELY HAD THE CHILDREN
I BELIEVE HAD THE CHILDREN'S
BEST INTENTIONS ALL THE TIME.
SHE WAS ALWAYS LOOKING OUT FOR
THEM.
JUST A VERY SAD THING.
>> YOU MUST BE EXHAUSTED, AND
I'M GOING TO LET YOU GO.
I APPRECIATE YOU TALKING
TONIGHT, AND THANK YOU.
I REALLY -- I JUST WISH YOU AND
YOUR FAMILY A LOT OF STRENGTH.
THANK YOU.
>> MY FAMILY IS ONE OF THE LUCKY
ONES, ANDERSON.
UNFORTUNATELY, THERE ARE A LOT
OF PEOPLE, YOU KNOW, THAT AREN'T
SO LUCKY TONIGHT IN TOWN, BUT
THANK YOU, AND I -- WE PRAY FOR
ALL OF THE FAMILIES THAT ARE OUT
THERE TONIGHT.
>> YEAH.
I THINK THERE ARE A LOT OF
PRAYERS AROUND THE WORLD TONIGHT
FOR THE FAMILIES, AMY, THANK
YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> IT IS FRANKLY UNBELIEVABLE.
LET'S GO BACK TO SOLEDAD.
>> IT REALLY IS.
IT REALLY IS.
AND IT'S ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE I
THINK TO FATHOM WHAT THE PEOPLE
OF NEWTOWN ARE GOING THROUGH NOW
AND WHAT THEY ARE GOING TO BE
GOING THROUGH IN THE NEXT DAYS
AND WEEKS, ESPECIALLY THE
PARENTS AND SIBLINGS AND FAMILY
MEMBERS OF LITTLE CHILDREN WHO
DID NOT SURVIVE THE MASSACRE
TODAY.
SO MANY LIVES WERE LOST, SO MANY
OTHER PEOPLE'S LIVES WERE JUST
CHANGED FOREVER.
FRIENDS AND NEIGHBORS AND IN
SOME CASES COMPLETE STRANGERS
GATHERED AND CONTINUE TO GATHER
AT THIS HOUR, HOLD EACH OTHER,
CRY, AND TO REMEMBER.
A VIGIL TONIGHT, TOOK PLACE AT A
LOCAL CHURCH AND JASON CARROLL
HAS BEEN THERE ALL DAY AND
THROUGH THE NIGHT AND AN UPDATE
ON HOW THAT WENT TONIGHT.
JASON, THE MOOD HAS GOT TO BE SO
SAD.
TELL ME A LITTLE BIT ABOUT
TONIGHT'S VIGIL.
>> YOU KNOW, I'VE SEEN A LOT OF
EMOTIONAL THINGS THROUGHOUT MY
LIFE, BUT TONIGHT WAS -- IT'S
REALLY HARD TO EXPLAIN.
THE VIGIL HERE TONIGHT.
SO MANY PEOPLE CAME OUT,
SOLEDAD.
THERE WASN'T ENOUGH ROOM FOR
EVERYBODY INSIDE ST. ROSA LINEA
CHURCH.
THEY CAME OUTSIDE.
STOOD IN THE FREEZING COLD.
HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE STOOD INSIDE
AND LISTENED.
WHEN THE VIGIL THAT LET OUT, ALL
OF THOSE STANDING OUTSIDE WENT
INSIDE AND YOU HEARD SOME
SINGING AT ONE POINT.
GROUPS BROKE OFF INTO SEPARATE
GROUPS AND STARTED SINGING.
PEOPLE REALLY CAME HERE TONIGHT,
AND I KNOW YOU JUST HEARD
ANDERSON GIVE THAT VERY
EMOTIONAL INTERVIEW.
PEOPLE CAME HERE LOOKING FOR
ANSWERS, JUST LIKE THAT MOTHER
WAS TRYING TO GIVE ANSWERS TO
HER DAUGHTER.
AND IT'S DIFFICULT, IT'S VERY
TOUGH TO TRY AND GET THOSE
ANSWERS AT THIS TIME.
PEOPLE CAME LOOKING FOR THAT.
THEY CAME TO LEAN ON EACH OTHER
AND THEY TURNED TO THEIR FAITH.
THIS IS SUCH A SMALL COMMUNITY
THAT IT'S THE KIND OF PLACE
WHERE LITERALLY SO MANY OF THE
PEOPLE CAME OUT TONIGHT KNEW
SOMEONE.
KNEW ONE OF THE FACULTY MEMBERS,
KNEW ONE OF THE CHILDREN.
THEY TALKED ABOUT ONE THE LITTLE
GIRLS WHO LOST HER LIFE WHO WAS
SUPPOSED TO BE IN A CHRISTMAS
PAGEANT HERE AT THE CHURCH.
SPOKE TO ANOTHER MAN WHO KNEW
THE PRINCIPAL.
HE WANTED TO SPEAK OUT BEFORE HE
WENT INTO THE VIGIL AND I WANT
YOU TO LISTEN TO A LITTLE BIT OF
THAT CONVERSATION.
>> DAWN, THE PRINCIPAL AT SANDY
HOOK, I HAD DINNER WITH HER LAST
SPRING, SHE WAS EXCITED,
EXUBERANT, AN EXCEPTIONAL
EDUCATOR.
IT'S SAD.
BUT MY PRAYERS WILL BE FOR OUR
COMMUNITY AS WELL.
>> ONE OF THE OTHER POINTS THAT
HE WANTED TO MAKE WAS THAT THIS
WAS A WOMAN WHO LOVED NOT ONLY
HER SCHOOL AND HER JOB, BUT SHE
LOVED ALL OF THE CHILDREN AT THE
SCHOOL AS WELL.
SOLEDAD.
>> SO, JASON, I KNOW YOU HAD A
CHANCE TO TALK TO THE DEACON,
AND I'M SURE HE WILL BE A FOCUS
OF MANY OF THE QUESTIONS THAT
PEOPLE ARE HAVING.
WHAT DID HE TELL YOU?
>> IT'S -- IT WAS DIFFICULT FOR
HIM.
HE BECAME EMOTIONAL DURING OUR
CONVERSATION.
HE SAID THAT AT LEAST 100 PEOPLE
HAD COME TO THE CHURCH DOORS
THROUGHOUT THE DAY LOOKING FOR
ANSWERS.
AND I SAID HOW DO YOU TRY AND
PROVIDE ANSWERS?
HE SAID IT'S TOO SOON TO COME UP
WITH SOME SORT OF A DEEP
PHILOSOPHICAL ANSWER AS TO WHY
THIS HAPPENED.
HE WAS ALSO FEELING THE EMOTION
OF WHAT HAS HAPPENED AS WELL.
HE KNEW SOME OF THE CHILDREN
THAT WERE KILLED, INCLUDING SOME
OF THE FACULTY MEMBERS.
HE SPOKE ABOUT ONE CHILD IN
PARTICULAR, WHO HE REMEMBERED
RECEIVING HER FIRST COMMUNE HERE
AT THE CHURCH, AND A CHILD WHO
REALLY LEFT AN IMPRESSION UPON
HIM, AND HE EXPLAINS THE REASON
WHY.
>> I HEARD ONE OF THE VICTIMS,
I'M NOT SURE ABOUT IT, BUT I
HEARD ONE OF THE VICTIMS
RECENTLY, I THINK IT WAS
BIRTHDAY MONEY, HER BIRTHDAY
GIFTS AND DONATED IT TO THE
PARISH TO GIVE FOR HURRICANE
SANDY VICTIMS.
SHE'S 6 YEARS OLD.
SO THAT'S -- THAT MAKES IT VERY,
VERY PERSONAL.
AND VERY INTIMATE.
>> HIS STRUGGLE IS THAT HE HAS
GOT TO BE A ROCK FOR THE
COMMUNITY NOW.
HE HAS GOT TO TRY TO KEEP IT
TOGETHER AS MORE PEOPLE COME TO
HIM TO LEAN ON HIM FOR EMOTIONAL
SUPPORT.
I ASKED HIM, I SAID WHAT DO YOU
DO?
I'M GOING TO GO HOME, HUG MY OWN
DAUGHTER, AND I'M GOING TO COME
BACK HERE AND BE THE SUPPORT
THIS COMMUNITY NEEDS.
SOLEDAD.
>> JASON CARROLL FOR US, THANK
YOU, JASON.
APPRECIATE THAT.
AND, ANDERSON, IT'S A QUESTION
THAT WE'RE ALL TRYING TO GET AN
ANSWER TO.
THE WHY BEHIND IT.
WE'VE TALKED A LITTLE BIT ABOUT
THE SHOOTER, BUT THE MOTIVATION
IS ALWAYS THE THING I DON'T
THINK ANYBODY IS CLOSE TO
UNDERSTANDING AT THIS POINT.
>> YEAH, AND MAY NEVER.
I MEAN, YOU KNOW, SOMETIMES
THERE ISN'T ANY WHY.
BUT WE'LL CONTINUE TO
INVESTIGATE, SOLEDAD, WE'LL COME
BACK TO YOU SHORTLY.
AUTHORITIES HAVE NOT YET
RELEASED THE NAME OF THE
VICTIMS, THE PROCESS OF
IDENTIFICATION CONTINUES AT THIS
HOUR.
THOSE CHILDREN'S LITTLE BODIES
ARE STILL INSIDE THAT SCHOOL AND
WILL BE THROUGHOUT THE EVENING.
AS WE LEARN WHO THEY ARE, WHEN
IT'S APPROPRIATE, WE'LL FOCUS ON
THE LIVES.
WE'LL TELL YOU ABOUT THEM WHEN
WE LEARN ABOUT THEM, WHAT
PARENTS WANT TO KNOW ABOUT THEM.
THE VICTIMS WE WANT HISTORY TO
REMEMBER AND HONOR.
ACCORDING TO WITNESSES, THE
SCHOOL'S PRINCIPAL ARE AMONG THE
DEAD.
YOU HEARD PARENTS TALK ABOUT
TONIGHT.
SHE BECAME THE PRINCIPAL AT
SANDY HOOK IN 2010.
SHE ARRIVED WITH 12 YEARS OF
EXPERIENCE AS A SCHOOL
ADMINISTRATOR, A MOM RAISING TWO
DAUGHTERS, THREE STEPDAUGHTERS
ACCORDING TO A LOCAL PAPER.
AND A LOT OF FOLKS WHO WORKED
WITH DAWN SAID SHE WAS EXTREMELY
PASSIONATE ABOUT HER JOB.
AN EXPERT ON CURRICULUM, FUN,
BUT A FIRM LEADER.
ONE FRIEND SAID SHE WAS THE KIND
OF PERSON YOU WOULD WANT TO BE
EDUCATING YOUR KIDS, AND THE
KIDS LOVED HER.
EVEN LITTLE KIDS KNOW WHEN
SOMEONE CARES BE B THEM, AND
THAT WAS HER.
SHE POSTED MESSAGES AND PHOTOS
ABOUT EVENTS AND DEVELOPMENTS AT
THE SCHOOL.
ON AUGUST 24th, SHE TWEETED,
WELCOMING OUR KINDERS THIS
MORNING.
74 NEW OPPORTUNITIES TO INSPIRE
LIFE LONG LEARNING, TALKING
ABOUT THE NEW KINDERGARTEN
CLASS.
SHE HAD RECENTLY INSTALLED A NEW
SECURITY SYSTEM WHERE ALL
VISITOR HAS TO RING A DOORBELL
AND WAIT TO BE BUZZED IN.
TWO WITNESSES TOLD OUR SISTER
NETWORK HLN THAT THE GLASS
ENTRANCE WAS SHOT OUT OR SMASHED
ALLOWING THE GUNMAN TO GET INTO
THE BUILDING.
WE DON'T HAVE ANY PHOTOGRAPHS OF
THE OTHER VICTIMS ACCORDING TO
WITNESSES, MARY SHERLOCK, THE
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST, 56 YEARS
OLD.
AT SANDY HOOK 18 YEARS, SHE HAD
A MASTER'S AND A SIX YEAR
PROFESSIONAL DEGREE.
WIFE AND MOM.
MOTHERED TO HER HUSBAND BILL FOR
MORE THAN 30 YEARS.
TWO GROWN DAUGHTERS, THE OLDEST
WORKS AS A HIGH SCHOOL CHORUS
TEACHER IN NEW JERSEY.
MARY SHERLOCK AND DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG, WE WILL REMEMBER
THEM.
WHEN WE COME BACK, MORE OF
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S EMOTIONAL
REACTION.
WE WANT TO PLAY HIS COMPLETE
COMMENTS AND MORE FROM THE
PARENTS AS WELL.
>> IT'S NOT -- IT'S NOT
SOMETHING YOU SHAKE OFF VERY
EASILY AND CERTAINLY NOT FOR
LITTLE PEOPLE AND WE LOST A LOT
OF BABIES TODAY IN THIS TOWN,
AND THERE ARE A LOT OF VERY SAD
FAMILIES, AND AS EVERYONE CAN
THINK, YOU NEVER THINK IT'S
GOING TO HAPPEN, BUT BASICALLY
IT HAPPENS ALL OVER THE WORLD AT
THIS POINT.
Bye!
Santa, we made a video for
your trip!
Yeah, you can watch it on your
sleigh!
OK!
Here you go.
Aw, thanks elves.
I also made you a video.
You are so sweet.
But you probably shouldn't watch
it on the sleigh.
Say goodbye to Santa boys!
Bye!
Good bye Santa!
Exclusively at AT&T, buy any
Samsung Galaxy smartphone,
get up to $100 off a second
msung Galaxy device.
>>> IT DOESN'T EVEN SEEM REAL.
IT JUST DOES NOT EVEN SEEM LIKE
IT'S POSSIBLE.
YOU READ IT IN THE PAPER, SEE IT
ON THE NEWS, YOU'RE LIKE OH, MY
GOD, THAT POOR FAMILY.
AND SOMETHING HAPPENS SO CLOSE
TO HOME, IT'S LIKE I THINK I'M
STILL IN SHOCK, TO BE HONEST
WITH YOU.
>> WELL, NO DOUBT A LOT OF
PEOPLE FEELING THE IMPACT SAME
WAY TONIGHT.
THE MASSACRE INSIDE THE SCHOOL,
THE DEADLIEST ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
SHOOTING IN AMERICAN HISTORY.
ALL THE WORDS SPOKEN TODAY, AND
ALL OF THE WORDS I'M SPEAKING
TONIGHT IN THIS HOUR, THEY ALL
SOUND SO SMALL IN THE FACE OF
THIS HORROR.
20 LITTLE CHILDREN, 7 ADULTS.
LAST NIGHT ALIVE, GETTING READY
FOR ANOTHER DAY OF SCHOOL,
TONIGHT THEY ARE GONE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SPOKE TO THE
NATION EARLIER, WE PLAYED SOME
OF IT BEFORE THE TOP OF THE
PROGRAM.
BUT I THINK IT'S WORTH HEARING
ALL OF WHAT HE SAID.
>> THIS AFTERNOON I SPOKE WITH
GOVERNOR MALLOY, FBI DIRECTOR
MUELLER.
I OFFERED GOVERNOR MALLOY MY
CONDOLENCES ON BEHALF OF THE
NATION AND MADE IT CLEAR HE WILL
HAVE EVERY SINGLE RESOURCE HE
NEEDS TO INVESTIGATE THIS
HEINOUS CRIME, CARE FOR THE
VICTIMS, COUNCIL THEIR FAMILIES.
WE HAVE ENDURED TOO MANY OF
THESE TRAGEDIES IN THE PAST FEW
YEARS, AND EACH TIME I LEARN THE
NEWS, I REACT NOT AS A
PRESIDENT, BUT AS ANYBODY ELSE
WOULD, AS A PARENT, AND THAT WAS
ESPECIALLY TRUE TODAY.
I KNOW THAT THERE IS NOT A
PARENT IN AMERICA WHO DOESN'T
FEEL THE SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF
THAT I DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM, BIRTHDAYS,
GRADUATIONS, WEDDINGS, KIDS OF
THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS, MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES TO HELPING
OUR CHILDREN FULFILL THEIR
DREAMS, SO OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN
TODAY FOR THE PARENTS AND
GRANDPARENTS, SISTERS AND
BROTHERS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN, AND FOR THE FAMILIES
OF THE ADULTS WHO WERE LOST.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN FOR THE
PARENTS OF THE SURVIVORS AS
WELL.
FOR AS BLESSED AS THEY ARE TO
HAVE THEIR CHILDREN HOME
TONIGHT, THEY KNOW THAT THEIR
CHILDREN'S INNOCENCE HAS BEEN
TORN AWAY FROM THEM TOO EARLY,
AND NO WORDS WILL EASE THEIR
PAIN.
AS A COUNTRY, WE HAVE BEEN
THROUGH THIS TOO MANY TIMES.
WHETHER IT'S AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN OR A SHOPPING
MALL IN OREGON OR A TEMPLE IN
WISCONSIN, OR A MOVIE THEATER IN
AURORA OR A STREET CORNER IN
CHICAGO, THESE NEIGHBORHOODS ARE
OUR NEIGHBORHOODS, AND THESE
CHILDREN ARE OUR CHILDREN.
AND WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO COME
TOGETHER AND TAKE MEANINGFUL
ACTION TO PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS, REGARDLESS OF THE
POLITICS.
THIS EVENING, MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT
IN AMERICA WILL DO.
WHICH IS HOLD OUR CHILDREN A
LITTLE TIGHTER, TELL THEM WE
LOVE THEM AND REMIND EACH OTHER
HOW DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT, AND THEY NEED ALL OF US
RIGHT NOW IN OUR DAYS TO COME,
THE COMMUNITY NEEDS TO US BE AT
OUR BEST AS AMERICANS, AND I
WILL DO EVERYTHING IN MY POWER
AS PRESIDENT TO HELP, BECAUSE
WHILE NOTHING CAN FILL THE SPACE
OF THE LOST CHILD OR LOVED ONE,
ALL OF US CAN EXTEND A HAND TO
THOSE IN NEED, TO REMIND THEM
THAT WE ARE THERE FOR THEM, THAT
WE ARE PRAYING FOR THEM, THAT
THE LOVE THEY FELT FOR THOSE
THEY LOST ENDURES NOT JUST IN
THEIR MEMORIES, BUT ALSO IN
OURS.
MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF THE
VICTIMS, AND IN THE WORDS OF
SCRIPTURE, HEAL THE
BROKENHEARTED AND BIND UP THEIR
WOUNDS.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA SPEAKING
EARLIER TODAY.
NOT JUST AS PRESIDENT, BUT AS A
FATHER OF TWO DAUGHTERS.
DENISE KORIAS' DAUGHTER GOES TO
SANDY HOOK.
WAS IN SCHOOL THIS MORNING.
WE SPOKE EARLIER TONIGHT.
DENISE, I CANNOT IMAGINE WHAT
THIS DAY HAS BEEN LIKE FOR YOU,
FOR YOUR CHILD.
HOW IS YOUR CHILD?
HOW ARE YOU?
>> I THINK EVERYONE IS COPING AS
BEST AS THEY POSSIBLY CAN, AND
IT IS SHOCKING WHEN IT HAPPENS
ANYWHERE.
SO WE'RE ALL TRYING TO WRAP OUR
ARMS AROUND THE SITUATION AS
BEST AS WE CAN.
>> DID -- DOES YOUR DAUGHTER
WANT TO TALK ABOUT IT WITH YOU?
OR ARE YOU ENCOURAGING HER TOO?
HOW DO YOU HANDLE THIS?
A LOT OF PARENTS AROUND THE
WORLD ARE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT TO SAY TO THEIR CHILD.
>> YOU KNOW, THE HARD THING FOR
ME IS, ANDERSON, I'M A NEW
YORKER, SO I'M VERY ACCUSTOMED
TO MANHATTAN AND ACCUSTOMED TO
ALWAYS TELLING MY KIDS TO BE
CAREFUL.
I GUESS YOU NEVER EXPECT IT TO
HAPPEN IN YOUR SCHOOL, AND AT
THE END OF THE DAY, YOU JUST --
I'M LETTING HER TALK.
SHE'S MENTIONED QUITE A BIT
ABOUT THE PRINCIPAL, WHO MANY OF
US HAVE WORKED WITH, AND I
ADORED HER.
I WORKED WITH HER PERSONALLY
WITH MY BUSINESS.
THAT IS ONE PERSON I KNOW WE'VE
LOST ON A PERSONAL LEVEL.
I KNOW THEY ARE GOING TO HAVE
COUNSELORS AT THE INTERMEDARY
SCHOOL TOMORROW, AND I ALREADY
TOLD MY CHILDREN, THEY ARE ALL
WELCOME TO GO THERE.
WE ARE PLANNING ON DOING THAT
TOMORROW, SO IF THEY NEED TO
SPEAK TO SOMEBODY, THEY WILL.
>> HAS YOUR DAUGHTER SAID MUCH
ABOUT WHAT SHE SAW OR WHAT SHE
HEARD?
>> SHE DID MENTION THAT SHE DID,
OF COURSE, HEAR GUNSHOTS, AND ON
THE SAME FLOOR, AND SHE -- HER
TEACHER, MANAGED TO TAKE TWO
CHILDREN OUT OF THE HALLWAY,
PULL THEM INTO THE CLASSROOM,
LOCK THE DOOR AND MOVE EVERYBODY
TO THE OTHER SIDE OF THE ROOM,
WHEN, YOU KNOW, IT WAS VERY
CONFUSING AS IT WOULD BE IN ANY
OF THESE CASES TO GO AND PICK UP
YOUR CHILD, ONCE WE FIGURED OUT
THAT EVERYTHING WAS DISPATCHED
TO SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY, I WAS
ONE OF THE FIRST PARENTS THERE
ALONG WITH A FRIEND OF MINE, WE
BOTH FIGURED OUT WHAT WAS GOING
ON, RAN OVER THERE, THEY WERE
VERY SMART TO GET THEM OUT OF
THE BUILDING, MOVED THEM OVER TO
THE FIREHOUSE.
YOU COULD SEE MY DAUGHTER'S
TEACHER WAS VISIBLY UPSET AS
WELL AS THE CHILDREN THERE.
SHE DID A VERY HEROIC THING.
PULLED TWO KIDS OUT OF THE
HALLWAY, SHOVED THEM INTO THE
CLASSROOM AND LOCKED THAT DOOR.
THE KIDS WILL SUFFER FROM THIS.
LIKE EVERYTHING ELSE, A
PSYCHOLOGICAL EVENT THAT WILL
TAKE TIME FOR HEALING AND AS
LONG AS EVERYONE GETS THE PROPER
HELP, IT'S NOT SOMETHING YOU
SHAKE OFF VERY EASILY AND
CERTAINLY NOT FOR LITTLE PEOPLE
AND WE LOST A LOT OF BABIES
TODAY IN THIS TOWN AND THERE ARE
A LOT OF VERY SAD FAMILIES, AND
AS EVERYONE CAN THINK, YOU NEVER
THINK IT WILL HAPPEN, BUT
BASICALLY IT HAPPENS ALL OVER
THE WORLD AT THIS POINT, SO WE
HAVE TO BE VERY COGNIZANT OF
MENTAL HEALTH AND GUN CONTROL IN
MY EYES AND HOW SCHOOLS ARE
LOCKED UP THESE DAYS.
AND IT'S UNFORTUNATE.
YOU WOULDN'T THINK TO TAKE YOUR
CHILDREN TO SCHOOL YOU HAVE TO
WORRY ABOUT SOMEONE GOING IN AND
BLOWING THEM ALL UP.
IT'S AN UNFORTUNATE STATE OF
AFFAIRS, BUT, UNFORTUNATELY,
IT'S OUR REALITY THESE DAYS.
>> DENISE, I'M SORRY THAT
REALITY WAS VISITED UPON YOUR
DAUGHTER TODAY.
AND EVERYBODY ELSE.
AND I WISH YOU STRENGTH AND
PEACE IN THE DIFFICULT DAYS
AHEAD.
THANK YOU FOR TALKING TONIGHT.
>> OH, THANK YOU SO MUCH,
ANDERSON.
>> AND THERE WILL BE A LOT OF
DIFFICULT DAYS AHEAD.
LET'S GO BACK TO SOLEDAD.
>> NO QUESTION ABOUT THAT.
SO, ANDERSON, AS WORD START TO
SPREAD THROUGHOUT THE STATE
TODAY, SO DID THE SHOCK, SO DID
THE HORROR AND NOW THERE IS THE
GRIEVING.
>> YOU CAN NEVER BE PREPARED FOR
THIS KIND OF INCIDENT.
WHAT HAS HAPPENED, WHAT HAS
TRANSPIRED AT THAT SCHOOL
BUILDING, WILL LEAVE A MARK ON
THIS COMMUNITY AND EVERY FAMILY
IMPACTED.
I ONLY ASK THAT ALL OF OUR
FELLOW CITIZENS HERE IN THE
UNITED STATES AND AROUND THE
WORLD, WHO HAVE ALREADY OFFERED
THEIR ASSISTANCE REMEMBER ALL OF
THE VICTIMS IN THEIR PRAYERS.
>> THAT WAS CONNECTICUT'S
GOVERNOR, DAN MALLOY SPEAKING
EARLIER TODAY.
HE SAID HIS MAIN RESPONSIBILITY
NOW IS THE INVESTIGATION ALONG
WITH LOCAL AND FEDERAL
AUTHORITIES.
I WANT TO EMPHASIZE ONCE AGAIN
THAT IS THE FOCUS NOW.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI, HANDLING OUR
COVERAGE OF THE INVESTIGATION.
LET'S FOCUS FIRST ON WHAT WE
KNOW ABOUT THE SHOOTER.
>> NOT VERY MUCH.
THAT HE IS 20 YEARS OLD, WE
UNDERSTAND THAT HE CAME TO THE
SCHOOL WITH THREE WEAPONS, TWO
OF THEM WERE HANDGUNS, ONE
DESCRIBED AS A GLOCK.
ONE DESCRIBED AS A SIG SAUER,
AND ANOTHER ONE NOT FOUND IN THE
CLASSROOM WITH HIM, BUT INSTEAD
WAS FOUND IN A CAR OUTSIDE THE
SCHOOL, AND THAT IS CALLED
A .223 BUSHMASTER, A SEMI
AUTOMATIC WEAPON.
IT SEEMS THOSE GUNS WERE NOT
REGISTERED TO HIM.
BUT WE ARE TOLD ACCORDING TO OUR
LAW ENFORCEMENT SOURCES THEY
BELONG TO HIS MOTHER WHICH IS --
DON'T HAVE AN EXPLANATION FOR
THAT RIGHT NOW.
>> WERE ALL THOSE GUNS LEGALLY
PURCHASED IN THIS STATE?
>> YES, THEY WERE LEGALLY
PURCHASED AND PURCHASED IN THE
STATE OF CONNECTICUT.
WE BELIEVE HE MIGHT HAVE BEEN
LIVING WITH HIS MOTHER.
OUR SOURCES TELL US HIS MOTHER'S
BODY WAS FOUND INSIDE A
RESIDENCE AND SHE LIVES IN THIS
AREA, SO IT'S POSSIBLE HE LIVED
WITH HIS MOTHER.
STILL WAITING ON THAT DETAIL.
>> SOME CONFUSION AS WELL WITH
HIS BROTHER.
POLICE WENT TO HOBOKEN TO DO AN
INVESTIGATION THERE, AND TOOK
THE BROTHER OFF FOR QUESTIONING
AS WELL.
>> THE BROTHER IS OLDER, 24
YEARS OLD, HE DOES LIVE IN AN
APARTMENT IN HOBOKEN, AND THEY
DID GO TO HIM TO ASK HIM
QUESTIONS ABOUT HIS BROTHER.
EVERYBODY TIGHTLIPPED ABOUT
EXACTLY WHAT HE TOLD THE
AUTHORITIES.
BUT ALSO HIS FATHER HAS BEEN
QUESTIONED AS WELL.
HIS FATHER IS DIVORCED FROM THE
MOTHER WHO WAS KILLED IN THIS
INCIDENT AND WE'RE SIMPLY TRYING
TO FIND OUT MORE ABOUT THAT AS
WELL.
>> SUSAN CANNDIOTTI, THE
INVESTIGATION CONTINUES.
THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER'S MOTHER,
WE'LL GET MORE INFORMATION ON
THAT RIGHT BACK TO ANDERSON FOR
MORE.
>> SOLEDAD, AS WE MENTIONED,
JUST IN CASE YOU JOINED US.
WE'RE INTENTIONALLY LIMITING THE
USE OF THE KILLER'S NAME.
WE DON'T WANT TO USE IT OVER AND
OVER AGAIN.
WE ARE TRYING TO LEARN MORE
ABOUT WHAT LED THIS PERSON TO
THE SCHOOL.
DREW GRIFFIN JOINS US LIVE.
>> HAVING COVERING SO MANY OF
THESE, A SHOOTER WITH POSSIBLE
MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES, A FAMILY
TRYING TO DEAL WITH THOSE
ISSUES, SOMETHING SNAPS, GUNS
EASILY ACCESSED AND WE HAVE THE
OUTBURST OF VIOLENCE IN THE CASE
OF THIS 20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER,
BEGINNING PLAY OUT IN EXACT THAT
WILL ORDER.
HERE IS WHAT WE DO KNOW.
THE 20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER HAD AN
OLDER BROTHER.
THAT BROTHER REPORTEDLY TOLD ABC
NEWS THAT THE SHOOTER HAD A
PERSONALITY DISORDER AND ALSO
MENTIONED AUTISM.
CNN HEARD THAT SAME INFORMATION
FROM A MAN WHO CALLED HIMSELF A
FRIEND OF THE SHOOTER'S IN
NEWTOWN WHERE THE SHOOTER LIVED.
WE CAN CONFIRM THE GUNS, TWO
HANDGUNS AND SEMI AUTOMATIC
RIFLE WERE LEGALLY OWNED BY THE
SHOOTER'S MOTHER, NOW DECEASED,
YOU CAN SEE THE PICTURE OF THE
GUN THERE, AND SOMEWHAT STANDARD
IN THESE CASES, WE FIND PEOPLE
THAT ARE SHOCKED THAT THE
PARTICULAR SHOOTER COULD HAVE
BEEN INVOLVED IN ANYTHING LIKE
THIS, AS IS THE CASE WITH ONE OF
THE SHOOTER'S FORMER CLASSMATES
AND FORMER SCHOOL BUS DRIVER.
>> HE WAS JUST A KID.
>> JUST A KID?
>> JUST A KID.
>> NEVER ANTI SOCIAL?
>> NO, NO.
>> TROUBLE MAKER?
>> NO, DEFINITELY NOT.
>> NOTICEABLE?
DID HE JUST KIND OF BLEND INTO
THE BACKGROUND?
>> YEAH.
NOTHING THAT WOULD WARRANT ANY
OF THIS.
>> HE WENT AFTER HER MOM AND HER
CLASS OF KIDS, CAN YOU WRAP YOUR
HEAD AROUND THAT?
>> NO, I CANNOT.
I DON'T KNOW WHO WOULD DO
ANYTHING LIKE THIS?
>> YOUR GENERAL SENSE IS WHAT?
>> THIS IS -- THIS IS
UNSPEAKABLE.
WHEN I FIRST HEARD ABOUT IT --
I'M STILL IN SHOCK.
EXCUSE ME A MOMENT.
I WANT TO GO.
>> HE WAS A NICE KID.
VERY POLITELY.
SHE RAISED VERY NICE BOYS TO ME.
THAT'S WHY I THINK IT'S A SHOCK.
TO EVEN KNOW THEM AND REALIZE
WHO THEY ARE, AND WHAT HE DID.
YOU CAN'T UNDERSTAND WHAT
HAPPENED THAT HE SNAPPED, WHAT
HAVE YOU, AND TOOK SUCH INNOCENT
LIVES.
>> SO WHAT CAN WE EXPECT?
WELL, ANDERSON, AS WE'VE LEARNED
IN THE OTHER CASES, VIRGINIA
TECH, THE SHOOTING OF
CONGRESSMAN GIFFORDS, THE MASS
KILLING AT THE MOVIE THEATER IN
AURORA, COLORADO, IN THE COMING
DAYS, MAYBE BY TOMORROW, WE'LL
SEE MULTIPLE WARNING SIGNS,
DANGEROUS MESSAGES, IGNORED OR
PERHAPS OR EVEN PRACTICE
SESSIONS OR AN OBSESSION WITH
THE MOM'S GUNS THAT WEREN'T
TAKEN SERIOUSLY OR THE FAMILY IN
MANY CASES DOESN'T KNOW HOW TO
HANDLE THE SITUATION.
THEY DON'T HAVE ANYWHERE TO TURN
AND THERE WILL NEVER BE AN
ANSWER OR EXPLANATION THAT COULD
BE ANYWHERE NEAR GOOD ENOUGH FOR
THE VICTIMS' FAMILIES TO
UNDERSTAND THIS, BECAUSE IN A
LOT OF CASES, IT'S JUST
SENSELESS AND IT'S NEVER GOING
TO BE UNDERSTOOD.
>> YEAH, AND HEARING THE -- ONE
OF THE PEOPLE SAY AUTISTIC, OR
COULD BE AUTISTIC, THAT -- I
MEAN, I HAVE NEVER HEARD OF
SOMEBODY AUTISTIC DOING
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
IT DOESN'T SEEM LIKE IT JIVES.
>> IT'S TWO SEPARATE THINGS.
THE BROTHER SAID PERSONALITY
DISORDER AND ALSO AUTISTIC.
WE'RE NOT TRYING TO PUT THOSE
TOGETHER OR SAY ONE LEADS TO THE
OTHER.
>> GOT IT.
>> BUT SOME HINTS, EARLY HINTS,
LIKE WE'VE SEEN IN THE OTHER
CASES, EARLY HINT WHERE THERE IS
SOME SORT OF MENTAL ISSUE GOING
ON AND WE LEARN AS THINGS GO ON
THAT THERE ARE WARNING SIGNS.
THAT'S WHAT I EXPECT.
THAT'S WHAT I'VE SEEN OTHER
EXPERTS EXPECT TALKING ABOUT
THIS.
>> AND THERE WILL BE DEBATE OVER
GUN ISSUES, GUN CONTROLS.
CONNECTICUT HAS VERY STRICT GUN
LAWS AND THESE GUNS WERE LEGALLY
PURCHASED AS FAR AS WE KNOW BY
THE MOTHER.
>> IF YOU WERE GOING TO MAKE A
GUN LAW TO PREVENT THIS, YOU
WOULD HAVE TO TAKE THIS WOMAN'S
LEGALLY OWNED GUNS AWAY THE
REASON WE FOUND OUT SO SOON
WHERE THESE GUNS CAME FROM,
CONNECTICUT HAS IT'S OWN
REGISTRY, YOU HAVE TO HAVE A
CERTIFICATE TO OWN A HANDGUN
THAT COMES WITH A -- A TEST --
NOT A TEST, BUT A CLASS.
A HANDGUN SAFETY CLASS.
NO ONE UNDER 21 CAN OWN A
HANDGUN AND THEY HAVE AN ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN.
THIS ASSAULT RIFLE, I DON'T HAVE
THE DETAILS IF IT WAS LEGALLY
OWNED, SHE MUST HAVE OWNED IT
BEFORE 1993 AND ALSO HAD A
CERTIFICATE OF POSSESSION
REGISTERED WITH THE STATE.
SOME OF THE OLDER GUNS WERE
GRANDFATHERED IN.
CAN'T HAVE AN ASSAULT WEAPON
PURCHASED IN CONNECTICUT AS I
READ FROM THE LAW.
>> HOW WERE THEY STORED?
IN A LOCKED BOX?
A LOT WE DON'T KNOW.
DREW, APPRECIATE IT.
>>> FOR PARENTS, THE ORDEAL
BEGAN WITH THE WORD THAT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WAS ON
LOCKDOWN.
THE FIRST WORD THAT PARENTS GOT.
WHEN WE COME BACK, WE'LL HAVE
MORE ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
THROUGHOUT THE DAY.
of Washington about the future
of Medicare and Social Security.
ANNCR: But you deserve straight
talk about the options on the...
table and what they mean for you
and your family.
ANCR: AARP is cutting through
all the political spin.
Because for our 37 million
members, only one word counts.
Get the facts at earnedasay.org.
Let's keep Medicare...
and Social Security strong for
generations to come.
>>> I WAS IN NEW YORK, AND MY
WIFE CALLED ME IN HISSTERRICS,
SO I RUSHED HOME, AND SHE -- SHE
HEARD SOME BANGS AND SHE WENT
RUNNING INTO A BATHROOM.
>> IT WAS FRIGHTENING, IT WAS
LIKE MY HEART STOPPED BEATING.
I CAN'T EVEN EXPLAIN IT.
>> JASON CARROLL GAVE US A LOOK
INSI
INSIDE THE VIGIL TONIGHT.
WE'RE JOINED BY THE CHURCH'S
PASTO
PASTOR.
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO A PARENT?
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO A PARENT WHO
IS GOING THROUGH THE WORST
POSSIBLE KIND OF GRIEF
IMAGINABLE?
>> YOU KNOW, I HAD A NUMBER OF
CONVERSATIONS WITH PARENTS
TODAY.
A NUMBER OF PEOPLE BELONG TO THE
PARISH COMMUNITY.
THE WORDS ARE FEW.
WHAT CAN YOU SAY?
MANY SAID THANK YOU FOR MANY
HERE WITH US.
WE PRAYED TOGETHER, HUGGED EACH
OTHER, A LOT OF TEARS.
CERTAINLY A LOT OF EMOTION, AND
I -- I DON'T REALLY THINK IT'S
SETTLED INTO THEIR LIVES.
THEIR CHILD HAS BEEN TAKEN FROM
THEM.
I MUST SAY FOR THE PARENTS I
SPOKE WITH TODAY, THERE WAS A
TREMENDOUS AMOUNT OF LOVE FOR
THESE CHILDREN, AND I KNOW THAT
THE DAYS AHEAD ARE GOING TO BE
VERY, VERY DIFFICULT.
WE AS A COMMUNITY, CERTAINLY AS
A CHURCH COMMUNITY WILL BE VERY
PRESENT TO THEM.
BUT THE WORDS?
WHAT CAN YOU SAY AT A TIME LIKE
THIS?
>> THERE ARE A LOT OF PARENTS
WRESTLING AROUND THE COUNTRY AND
AROUND THE WORLD WITH WHAT ARE
THEY GOING TO SAY TO THEIR
CHILDREN WHO ASK THEM QUESTIONS
ABOUT THIS.
WHAT DO YOU RECOMMEND FOR PEOPLE
TO SAY TO THEIR KIDS.
NOT KIDS AT NEWTOWN AT THE
SCHOOL, BUT CHILDREN WHO HEAR
ABOUT THIS, WANT TO KNOW IF THEY
ARE SAFE, WANT TO KNOW ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED?
>> THAT'S THE ONE THING YOU HAVE
TO ASSURE THEM.
SOME OF THE CIRCUMSTANCES ARE
BEYOND ANY HUMAN CONTROL.
WE HAVE TO TEACH THESE CHILDREN
THEY HAVE TO TRUST.
YOU KNOW, I KNOW IT'S A
DIFFICULT WORLD IN WHICH WE LIVE
AND VERY DIFFICULT TO TRUST
EVERYONE, BUT THEY HAVE TO HAVE
FAITH, FAITH IN GOD AND FAITH
WITH EACH OTHER AND I HOPE
PARENTS LEARN THE VALUE OF
FAMILY AND KEEP THE VALUES
STRAIGHT.
THE CHILDREN NEED TO KNOW THEY
ARE LOVED AND THEY ARE IN AN
ENVIRONMENT WHERE THEY CAN GROW
UP TO BE PRODUCTIVE CITIZENS.
I DON'T KNOW HOW YOU TAKE FEAR
OUT OF A CHILD'S HEART EXCEPT BY
LOVE.
AND THESE CHILDREN WERE DEEPLY
LOVED BY THEIR PARENTS.
I'M SURE WHEN THEY DROPPED THEIR
CHILDREN OFF AT THE SCHOOL, THE
LAST THING ON THEIR MINDS IS
THIS THE WAY THE DAY WOULD END.
I HOPE PARENTS TAKE THE
OPPORTUNITY TO TALK TO THEIR
CHILDREN ABOUT THE IMPORTANCE OF
BEING FAMILY AND THE IMPORTANCE
OF TRUSTING AND LOVING EACH
OTHER.
>> ONE OF THE THINGS I WAS
THINKING ABOUT TODAY, AFTER THE
AURORA SHOOTING IN AURORA,
COLORADO, THEY HAD A SORT OF
MEMORIAL SERVICE, AND I REMEMBER
THE SPEAKERS WOULD READ THE NAME
OF EACH PERSON WHO WAS KILLED,
AND THEN THE CROWD WOULD SHOUT
BACK, WE WILL REMEMBER.
WE WILL REMEMBER YOU.
THAT WAS SO POWERFUL.
AND I KEPT THINKING ABOUT THAT
TODAY, OUR COVERAGE TONIGHT.
WE EMPHASIZE THE IMPORTANCE OF
REMEMBERING THE VICTIMS.
AND WE SAW THAT TONIGHT AT THE
VIGIL, PEOPLE WERE LITERALLY --
THEY WERE OUTSIDE.
IT WAS SO MANY PEOPLE WANTING TO
GO.
THEY COULDN'T FIT IN.
WHAT WAS YOUR MESSAGE TONIGHT?
>> OUR MESSAGE, I THUT THIS WAS
A DAY ABOUT HEARTS.
I WITNESSED THIS MORNING, BEING
WITH THE FAMILIES, WITH THEM FOR
ALMOST SIX HOURS.
COMPASSIONATE HEARTS, BROKEN
HEARTS, CARING HEARTS.
REALLY ABOUT LOVE IN SO MANY
WAYS, AND LOVE LOST, BUT LOVE
THAT WILL NEVER BE FORGOTTEN.
I ENCOURAGE PEOPLE TONIGHT --
WE'VE GOT TO DO SOMETHING ABOUT
VIOLENCE IN THIS COUNTRY,
VIOLENCE IN THE MEDIA, VIOLENCE
IN THE ENTERTAINMENT INDUSTRY.
IT IS FILLING THEIR HEADS WITH
AN AWARENESS THAT EVIL DOES
EXIST IN THIS WORLD, BUT THAT
GOOD ALWAYS CONQUERS EVIL AND
THE ONLY WAY WE'LL CHANGE IS BY
COMING TOGETHER AS A COMMUNITY,
AND THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED
TONIGHT.
PEOPLE CAME TOGETHER TO SUPPORT
EACH OTHER AND TO ENCOURAGE EACH
OTHER.
TO LET EACH OTHER KNOW THERE IS
A BETTER WAY TO LIVE.
WE DON'T HAVE TO BE AFRAID IF WE
WORK TOGETHER AS A COMMUNITY.
>> MONSIGNOR, I KNOW IT'S BEEN A
LONG DAY FOR YOU, A HORRIFIC DAY
FOR YOU.
I APPRECIATE YOU TAKING THE TIME
TO TALK TO US.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> AGAIN, SOLEDAD, AS WE'VE BEEN
SAYING ALL NIGHT LONG AND ALL
DAY LONG, THERE WILL BE MANY
DIFFICULT DAYS AHEAD.
>> NO QUESTION, FOR THOSE WHO
HAVE LOST CHILDREN AND THOSE
WHOSE CHILDREN SURVIVED.
TOUGH CONVERSATIONS.
MANY WERE TELLING US WHAT
HAPPENED WHEN THEY CAME RACING
TO THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THEY GOT WORD THAT THE SCHOOL
WAS ON LOCKDOWN AND THEY WERE
PANICKED.
SOME TRIED TO RUN TO THE SCHOOL.
SENT TO A NEARBY FIRE STATION,
COMPLETELY FRANTIC SCENE BY ALL
ACCOUNTS WE'VE HEARD.
PEOPLE HAD TO BASICALLY SIT AND
WAIT TO SEE IF THEIR CHILDREN
WERE ALIVE OR NOT.
EARLIER, I SPOKE WITH CHRISTINE
WILFORD ABOUT HER EXPERIENCE.
HER SON IS A SECOND GRADER AT
THE SCHOOL.
HOW ARE YOU DOING NOW?
>> IT'S STILL PROCESSING.
IT'S -- IT'S SCARY, SCARY.
NO WORDS.
>> HOW IS YOUR SON DOING?
ARE YOU ENCOURAGING HIM TO TALK
AND SHARE OR TRYING TO TAKE HIS
MIND OFF THE TERRIBLE THINGS
THAT HE WITNESSED AND
EXPERIENCES?
>> WE'VE DONE A LITTLE BIT OF
EACH.
TRY TO SPOIL HIM AND, YOU KNOW,
TAKE HIS MIND OFF, LET HIM PLAY
THE PS3, STUFF LIKE THAT, AND
THEN TRYING TO TALK AND PROCESS
WITH HIM, LETTING THEM KNOW WHEN
WE FOUND OUT ABOUT OTHER
CHILDREN THAT HE KNOWS.
>> YOU'VE GOTTEN AN ELECTRONIC
ALERT IS REALLY HOW YOU GOT THE
MESSAGE, A ROBOCALL.
HOW DID THAT COME ACROSS?
WHAT WAS SAID?
IT MUST HAVE BEEN THE MOST
TERRIFYING THING.
>> MY HUSBAND AND I WERE SITTING
THERE, AND A NEIGHBOR WAS OVER
AND WE GOT A ROBOCALL THAT ALL
NEWTOWN SCHOOLS WERE IN LOCKDOWN
DUE TO A REPORTED SHOOTING.
WE IMMEDIATELY GOT ONLINE.
MY NEIGHBOR CALLED HER HUSBAND
AND HE SAID HE HEARD IT WAS
SANDY HOOK.
WE HOPPED IN THE CAR AND WENT
DOWN.
>> THE SCHOOL WAS ON LOCKDOWN.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
>> I'M NOT SURE COMPLETELY WHAT
THAT MEANS.
WHEN I GOT THERE, ALL OF THE
CHILDREN EVACUATED WERE IN THE
FIREHOUSE.
WHICH IS CLOSE PITCH.
>> HOW ARE THE KIDS HOLDING UP?
>> IT VARIES.
MY SON SEEMED TO BE OKAY.
MOM, I'M OKAY, I'M SAFE.
HE GAVE ME A BIG HUG.
A LOT OF CHILDREN WERE CRYING
AND SCARED.
>> HOW DID HE DESCRIBE WHAT
HAPPENED?
>> HE SAID HE HEARD WHAT SOUNDED
LIKE LARGE PANS FALLING, JUST
LOUD NOISES.
HE SAID HIS TEACHER STEPPED
OUTSIDE THE CLASSROOM,
IMMEDIATELY CAME BACK IN AND
LOCKED THE DOOR AND HAD THEM ALL
GET INTO A CORNER AND SIT DOWN
AND JUST HAD THEM START READING
QUIETLY.
>> HOW MUCH TIME WENT BY BETWEEN
THAT HAPPENED AND BEFORE HE WAS
ABLE TO GET TO YOU?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
HE ISN'T ABLE TO PIECE HOW MUCH
TIME ACTUALLY PASSED.
HE SAID AFTER A LITTLE WHILE, A
POLICE OFFICER CAME AND TOOK
THEM OUT OF THE BUILDING AND
BROUGHT THEM TO THE FIREHOUSE.
>> WE KNOW THAT THE PRINCIPAL
HAD INSTALLED A SYSTEM WHERE YOU
HAVE TO BE BUZZED IN.
>> YES.
AND IT'S BEEN THAT WAY FOR THE
TWO YEARS WE'VE BEEN HERE.
YOU HAD TO RING A DOORBELL AND
BE LET IN, AND THE OFFICE IS
RIGHT IN FRONT OF THOSE DOORS,
THEY CAN LOOK OUT AND SEE WHO IS
AT THE DOOR?
>> ANY PARTICULAR REASON FOR
THAT?
IT'S VERY TYPICAL IN BIG CITIES,
BUT COMMUNITIES PRETTY RURAL, A
LITTLE BIT OF A RARITY
SOMETIMES?
>> I THINK THEY TAKE THE SAFETY
OF OUR CHILDREN VERY SERIOUS.
IT'S A FAIRLY LARGE SCHOOL.
THERE'S BETWEEN 500 AND 600
STUDENTS THERE, AND THEY WANT TO
KEEP CONTROL, AND, YOU KNOW WHO
IS IN THE BUILDING WITH OUR
CHILDREN.
>> I WAS TALKING TO THE STATE
POLICE, AND THEY SAID THEY ARE
PROCESSING THE SCENE STILL,
WHICH MEANS THERE ARE CHILDREN
STILL INSIDE.
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN TO YOUR SON
WHAT HAS HAPPENED ABOUT HIS
CLASSMATES?
>> WE -- WE ARE A FAIRLY
RELIGIOUS FAMILY AND WE JUST HAD
TALKED ABOUT THAT THEY HAD GONE
TO HEAVEN, AND TO, YOU KNOW, BE
WITH JESUS AND THAT'S ABOUT ALL
WE CAN SAY.
YOU KNOW, AND TALK ABOUT YOU'RE
NOT GOING TO SEE THEM ANYMORE
AND NOT GOING TO BE AROUND, AND
IT'S -- YOU REALLY JUST STRUGGLE
TO FIND THE WORDS, YOU KNOW, AS
TO WHAT HAPPENED.
>> YOU SHOULD KNOW THAT EVERYONE
IS SENDING THEIR WELL WISHES,
NOT JUST TO YOU AND YOUR FAMILY,
BUT TO THE COMMUNITY AS A WHOLE.
>> WE ARE A STRONG COMMUNITY.
A STRONG FAMILY COMMUNITY WITH A
LOT OF LOVE.
SO I THINK THAT WE'LL GET
THROUGH THIS SOMEHOW, SOME WAY.
>> CHRISTINE, THANKS SO MUCH.
WE APPRECIATE IT.
RIGHT BACK TO ANDERSON.
>> SOLEDAD, THANKS VERY MUCH.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
AMERICANS ARE ALWAYS READY TO
WORK HARD FOR A BETTER FUTURE.
SINCE AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL
WAS FOUNDED BACK IN 1894,
THEY'VE BEEN COMMITTED
TO PUTTING CLIENTS FIRST.
HELPING GENERATIONS
THROUGH TOUGH TIMES.
GOOD TIMES.
NEVER TAKING A BAILOUT.
THERE WHEN YOU NEED THEM.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
OVER THE CENTURIES.
THE STRENGTH OF
A GLOBAL FINANCIAL LEADER.
THE HEART OF
A ONE-TO-ONE RELATIONSHIP.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
SantHo, Ho, Ho!anta!
Santa!
Want to see some magic?
Watch this! Merry Chr...
(Crash) Ow!
I landed on my keys.
Did you get that?
Oh yeah.
That was amazing.
Here you go.
That was a fun trick!
See? Santa's okay.
Walk it off Santa.
Share videos instantly
with S Beam.
On the Galaxy SIII
and Note II.
For a limited time get two flip
covers for the price of one.
Exclusively at Verizon.
TALK ABOUT THE HEARTS OF
NEWTOWN, THE BROKEN HEARTS,
LOVING HEARTS AND SPOKE IN HOPES
OF HEALING HEARTS TONIGHT.
HERE IS MORE FROM THE VIGIL
TODAY.
♪
>> I WOULD LIKE TO SHARE WITH
YOU A LETTER FROM HIS HOLINESS,
POPE BENEDICT XVI, I WAS
PROMPTLY INFORMED OF THE
SHOOTING IN SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
I CONHAVE A MY HEARTFELT GRIEF
AND MY PERSONAL PRAYERS TO THE
VICTIMS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
TO ALL OF THOSE IN THE COMMUNITY
OF NEWTOWN AND ESPECIALLY THE