YOU A LETTER FROM HIS HOLINESS,
POPE BENEDICT XVI, I WAS
PROMPTLY INFORMED OF THE
SHOOTING IN SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
I CONHAVE A MY HEARTFELT GRIEF
AND MY PERSONAL PRAYERS TO THE
VICTIMS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
TO ALL OF THOSE IN THE COMMUNITY
OF NEWTOWN AND ESPECIALLY THE
PARISH OF ST. ROSE OF LIMA.
>> I HAVE NO WORDS THAT MAKE THE
PAIN OF WHAT HAPPENED TODAY EASY
TO BEAR.
I'M HEARTBROKEN, AS I KNOW ALL
OF YOU ARE.
NOTHING MORE HURTFUL OR TRAGIC
THAN THE LOSS OF INNOCENCE, BUT
NO MORE SO WHEN THOSE LOST ARE
YOUNG CHILDREN.
I'M HEARTBROKEN.
>> PEOPLE'S CHILDREN, BROTHERS
AND SISTERS, WERE TAKEN FROM
THEM.
PEOPLE'S SPOUSES.
THOSE TEACHERS AND
ADMINISTRATORS WERE TAKEN FROM
US.
>> I HAVE TO COMMEND ALL OF THE
FIRST RESPONDERS, BOTH STATE AND
LOCAL, AND CERTAINLY THE STAFF
OF THE SCHOOL.
THEY WERE THERE FOR THOSE
CHILDREN, WHICH IS WHAT TEACHERS
ARE ALL ABOUT.
AND IT WAS MOST OBVIOUS TODAY,
MOST OBVIOUS TODAY, WHAT THEY
REALLY ARE ABOUT AS TEACHERS.
TO ALL OF THEM, I SAY THANKS ON
BEHALF OF ALL OF US.
>> AND THAT DOES IT FOR US.
THANK YOU FOR WATCHING.
ERIN BURNETT "OUTFRONT" STARTS
NOW.
>>> BREAKING NEWS, MASSACRE IN
HERE IS WHAT WE KNOW.
THE 20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER HAD AN
MANY SAY THIS TRAGEDY DEMANDS
TOUGHER LEGISLATION AND INSIDE
THE WHITE HOUSE, A VIZ
APPROXIMATELY SHAKEN PRESIDENT
OBAMA OFFERED THESE WORDS ABOUT
THE MASS KILLING.
>>> THESE WERE BEAUTIFUL LITTLE
CHILDREN BETWEEN 5 AND 10 YEARS
OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS.
KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
MEN AND WOMEN WHO HAD DEVOTED
THEIR LIVES TO HELPING OUR
CHILDREN FULFILL THEIR DREAMS.
>> AN EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT OBAMA
REFLECTING HOW MOST OF THE
NATION HAD BEEN FEELING AND
TONIGHT, THIS IS HIS BROTHER,
RYAN LANZA BEING TAKEN INTO
REQUESTING TODAY.
I MUST THINK THERE ARE NEW
DETAILS ON THE SHOOTING.
SUSAN, A DESPERATE DAY.
THE SOFL AND THE TESTIMONY LIST
WITH FOUR CHILDREN WHAT DO WE
KNOW ABOUT THE PEPPER THAT'S
TORE OF THE HE'DOUS CRIME.
>> IT IS SO HEARD BREAKING,
PIERCE.
GUNMAN DRESSED IN BLACK FATIGUES
AND A MILITARY VEST OPENED FIRE
IN THE SCHOOL.
THE POLICE HAVE QUESTIONED HIS
FATHER AND HIS BROTHER.
FROM HIS APARTMENT IN HE BROKOB
NEW JERSEY.
THE FATHER WAS ALSO QUESTIONED
BY THAURTS HERE IN THE NEW
CONNECTICUT AREA.
THE FATHER HAS DIVORCED FROM
NANCY LANZA.
NOW SHE'S THE MOTHER OF THE TWO
WHO IS A SCHOOLTEACHER AND WHO
IS COUNTED AMONG THE DEAD.
HER BODY WAS FOUND IN A
RESIDENCE HERE IN THE NEW AREA
AS WELL.
BELIEVE IT OR NOT, THOSE WEAPONS
ACCORDING TO AUTHORITIES, WERE
BOTH BY THE MOTHER.
NOT BY THE SHOOTER.
DID HE LEAVE ANY NOTES BEHIND?
DID HE TELL ANYONE WHAT HE WAS
PLANNING TO DO?
AMONG THE MANY QUESTIONS WE ALL
HAVE TONIGHT.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I WANT TO GO TO ASHLEY BANFIELD.
ASHLEY, I WAS WATCHING EARLIER
WHEN YOU WERE SNEAKING AND I
THINK -- WHAT'S HAPPENING WITH
THEM, THE FACT THAT THEY WERE
OKAY.
BUT THIS IS EVERY APARTMENT'S
NIGHTMARE BODIES OF THE CHILDREN
ARE LYING THERE AND POLICE STILL
CALL IT A CRIME SCENE AND THE
PARENTS CAN'T EVEN SEE THEM.
THAT'S A BLOODY MATCH OFF.
>> NO OTHER WAY TO PUT IT.
UNIMAGINABLE HORROR.
AND I HAVE ANOTHER DETAIL I WANT
TO SHARE WITH YOU ABOUT HOW SOME
OF THESE PARENTS LEARNED THAT
THEY WOULDN'T BE SEEING THEIR
CHILDREN AGAIN.
I THINK YOU KNOW THE DETAIL THAT
MANY OF THE CHIRP WERE RUSHED
OUT OF THE SCHOOL, OUT OF THE
SANDY HOPE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL BY
THE POLICE AND TEACHERS AND THEY
RACED ON FOOT TO A NEAR BIFD
FIRE STATION THROUGHOUT THE DAY
THERE WAS AN AREA WITHIN THE
FIRE STATION WHERE THE CHILDREN
WERE KEPT AND THEY WERE SHOWN
MOVIES UNTIL THEIR PARENTS CAME
TO FIND THEM.
>> BUT PARENTS WERE MILLING AWAY
WHEN STUDENTS -- IT WAS QUITE A
CHAOTIC SCENE.
OVER THE COURSE OF THE DAY,
PARENTS ARRIVE AND CHIRPEN WERE
TAKEN A WAY.
ULTIMATELY THIS WAS A MOMENT
WHERE THEY HAD TO TELL THESE
WAITING PARENTS THERE WILL BE NO
MONTH REUNIONED TONIGHT TONIGHT.
I'VE TOLD FROM SOMEONE IN THAT
AREA BUT AT THE MOMENT THE
PARENTS WERE TOLD NO MORE
REUNIONS AND NO MORE CHILDREN
COMING.
AND THEN THERE WERE WHALES.
AND JUST A HORRIFYING MOMENT
BEING THE PARENTS WHO WAITED AND
WAITED AND WAITED, ONLY TO HEAR
THIS.
AND ULTIMATELY YOU SAID, PIERCE,
THEY KNOW THE BODIES OF THEIR
CHILDREN ARE STILL IN THAT
SCHOOL TONIGHT.
>> IT'S HARD TO IMAGINE ANYTHING
WORSE.
ASHLEY, THANK YOU FOR THAT.
WE'RE JOINED BY THE MAYOR.
MR. MAYOR THANKS FOR JOINING ME.
THIS IS ALMOST BEYOND
DESCRIPTION.
HOW IS THE COMMUNITY?
>> IT'S BEEN A HORRIFIC DOWN AND
PARTICULARLY THE TOWN OF NEWTOWN
AND OUR HEART GOES OUT TO THE
INDIVIDUALS THAT BECAME HOMELESS
TODAY AND THE OTHER KIDS WHO GO
STIFF.
I HAVE TO TELL YOU ON THE FIRST
O'CAMPAIGN -- HAVE BEEN
TREMENDOUS.
THE STAFF AT SCHOOL HAS BEEN
ABSOLUTELY HEROIC.
JUST AN ANSWER LET INTERNATIONAL
CRISIS.
.
>> I HAD THE HONOR OF WORKING
THE THE SAME SCHOOL SYSTEM AND
VERY CLOSE PROXIMITY TO DAWN WHO
PASSED AWAY TONIGHT.
SHE WAS A TEACHER IN THE PUBLIC
SCHOOL SYSTEM AND EL VATD UP THE
RANKS AND REACHED PRINCIPAL IN
NEW TOWN AND IT COMMITTED HARD
WORK DEDICATED EDUCATORS.
>> YOU COULD MAKE THAT.
>> APPRECIATE YOU JOINING ME,
MR. MAYOR AND I CAN ONLY WISH
YOU THE VERY BEST.
TRYING TO REBUILD THE COMMUNITY.
DID YOU KNOW IF THERE WERE ANY
PLANS FOR ANY MORE VIGILS
TOMORROW?
THAT.
>> THERE ARE VIGILS SCHEDULED
THROUGH THE THE COMMUNITY ALL
WEEKEND AND THERE IS A
SIMULTANEOUS VIGIL.
FOR EACH TOWN AND MAKES YOU
REALIZE, WE -- REFLECTING A
LITTLE BIT ABOUT OUR PUBLIC
POLICY POSITIONS IN TERMS AS
THEY RELATE TO GUN CONTROL AND
HOWIE'D HEAL THE FOLKS MENTALLY
DISABLED.
ONCE WE FULLY UNDERSTAND THE
HORRIFIC TRAGEDY, I THINK THE
CONVERSATION WILL BE STARTED
OVER THE NEXT WEEK.
>> THANKS FOR JOINING ME.
>> CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT IT WAS
LIKE IN THE SCHOOL.
SHOWS ME HER WITH HER MOTHER AND
THEY ARE HERE.
I MAY STOP FOR A FEW MOTHER'S
NIGHTMARE.
WHEN THE FIRST YOU HEARD ABOUT
IT AND HOW DID YOU HEAR.
>> I RECEIVED A CALL FROM THE
SCHOOL SYSTEM SAYING THAT THERE
WAS A SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN.
DIDN'T SAY THAT IT WAS A SCHOOL
BUT THE SCHOOLS WERE ON LOUK
DIOP I DIDN'T KNOW WHERE IT
HAPPENED AND THEN I GOT A TEXT
AND THEY SAID THAT SANDY THERE
HAD BEEN A SHOOTING SO I GOT IN
MY CAR AND I WEN OVER TO THE
SCHOOL AND THERE ARE ALSO STATE
POLICE AND FIRE AND NEWTOWN
POLICE.
SCENES OF COMPLETE CHAOS.
HOW QUICKLY WAS IT THAT YOU
REALIZED YOUR DAUGHTER WAS SAFE?
>> OKAY.
WHEN I GOT THERE THERE WAS
COMPLETE CHAOS BUT I SAW SOME
MOMS AND A NEIGHBOR.
AND I ASKED THEM WHAT HAD
HAPPENED AND THEY SAID THEY
DIDN'T KNOW.
BUT THAT THERE WAS A SHOOTING
THEY CARRIED OUT A LITTLE GIRL
AND IT LOOKED LIKE SHE WAS DEAD
SO I STANLTLY I PANICKED BECAUSE
MY BABY HEERP.
BUT THANKFULLY, NO SOONER HE HAD
THAT AND I LOOKED AT THE KIDS
BEING BROUGHT FROM THE SCHOOL OF
THE FIRE HOUSE AND I SAW HER
CLASS AND I SAID, WHERE IS
SOPHIA AND THEY SAID, SHE'S
OKAY, SHE'S COMING.
AND WE WERE AUTOMATIC TAKEN INTO
THE FOR HOUSE.
>> THIS MUST HAVE BEEN A
TERRIFYING DAY FOR YOU.
WHAT DID YOU THINK WAS
HAPPENING?
WERE YOU AWARE SOMEBODY WAS
FIRING A GUN AT THE SCHOOL?
NOT REALLY.
WHAT SHE TOLD ME WAS THEY HEARD
POPS IN THE HALLWAY AND THE
TEACHER AND THE TEACHER TOLD ME,
ALSO, COURTNEY MARTIN, SHE'S MY
HERO, THAT SHE LOCKED THE DOOR
IMMEDIATELY AND BROUGHT ALL THE
KIDS TO A CORNER OF THE ROOM
WHERE THEY STAYED THERE.
THEY WERE SCARED.
THEY WERE SHAKEN BUT THEY DIDN'T
KNOW WHAT WAS GOING ON UNTIL
LATER WHEN THEY WERE BROUGHT TO
THE FIRE HOUSE.
POLICE CAME AND KNOCKED ON THE
DOOR.
HE CAN COME OUT.
AND THEY GRIDDED HIM TO THE BACK
OF THE SCHOOL AND THEY WALKED
OVER TO THE FIRE HOUSE AND
THAT'S WHERE YOU CAUGHT UP WITH
SOPHIA -- EXTRAORDINARILY
TRAUMATIC EXPERIENCE FOR ALL
THOSE CHILDREN.
AND WHO SURVIVES THIS.
>> I THINK SHE'S NUMB RIGHT NOW.
SHE'S A PRETTY BRIGHT KID AND
SHE HAS A BIG SUPPORT STAFF AT
HOME AND WE LOVE HER VERY MUCH
AND SHE'LL BE FINE.
WHOOERP DEVASTATED FOR THE REST
OF THE FAMILIES BECAUSE WE DON'T
KNOW.
I DO MY CLOSE FRIENDS, THEIR
CHILDREN ARE OKAY.
BUT WE DON'T KNOW.
>> I JUST WONDERED WHAT THIS
SAYS ABOUT THAT HAPPENED TO HER
TODAY.
>> DO YOU WANT TO SAY ANYTHING?
>> I THINK SHE'S TOO COLD.
>> NO, I THINK SHE SHOULD
PROBABLY GO HOME WITH HER MOM.
IT'S BEEN A TERRIFYING WEEK.
AND I'M SO GRATEFUL THAT YOU
WERE ABLE TO SEE YOUR DAUGHTERER
THE.
>> THIS IS A CLOSE-KNIT SCHOOL
AND THIS IS DEVASTATING.
I'LL BE HERE FOR ANYBODY.
OUR PRAYERS GO OUT TO ALL THE
FAMILIES.
>> BRENDA, THANK YOU VERY MUCH
INDEED.
>> I'M THE LUCKIEST LADY.
>> THANKS FOR JOINING ME, I DO
APPRECIATE IT.
>> THANK YOU, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
>> LUCKY INDEED.
IS ADAM LANZA FORMER CLASSMATE,
ALEX ISRAEL.
ALEX, THANK FOR JOINING ME.
YOU, IN CHARACTER, IS THERE
SOMETHING YOU COULD HAVE EVER
PREDICTED THAT HE WOULD ONE DAY
FLIP AND DO SOMETHING AS
MONSTROUS AS THIS.
>> I DON'T KNOW IF YOU CAN EVER
PREDICT SOMETHING LIKE THAT
WOULD HAPPEN BUT I DON'T KNOW IF
I COULD PREDICT IT.
THERE WAS SOMETHING OFF ABOUT
HIM.
I ONLY KNEW HIM CLOSELY WHEN WE
WERE IN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
TOGETHER.
HE WAS ALWAYS A LITTLE BIT
DIFFERENT.
HE MOSTLY STAYED TO HIMSELF BUT
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU COULD HAVE
PREDICTED THIS.
>> HE WAS, BY ALL ACCOUNTS, A
PRETTY CLIFR I THINK PLAN?
A MATH GENIUS, APPARENTLY?
>> YEAH.
>> TELL ME ABOUT THAT SIDE OF
IT.
>> I WAS NEVER IN ANY OF HIS
CLASSES OR ANYTHING LIKE THAT,
YOU COULD DEFINITELY SAY HE WAS
A GENIUS.
DEFINITELY SOMETHING THERE THAT
WAS A LITTLE BIT ABOVE THE REST
OF US.
>> DID HE HAVE FRIENDS?
WAS HE SOCIAL?
>> I ALWAYS SAW HIM ALONE.
BUT I'M SURE -- I THINK HE WHAT
A FEW, MAYBE, CLOSE FRIENDS,
THROUGH SCHOOL OR HIS CLASSES.
BUT MOST OF THE TIME I SAW HIM
HE WAS ALONE, YEAH.
>> HOW WOULD YOU DESCRIBE HIS
PERSONALITY.
>> HE WAS REALLY QUIET AND KEPT
TO HIMSELF AND AP LITTLE IF I
JETTY AND A LITTLE UNEASY IF YOU
WERE TO LOOK AT HIM.
SOCIALLY NOT REALLY INTO GOING
OUT THERE AND MAKINGS MANY
FRIENDS AS EVERYONE WAS DOING IT
IN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND
O'MIDDLE SCHOOL.
>> DID YOU KNOW HIS FAMILY, HIS
MOTHER IN PARTICULAR?
>> I KNEW HER, WE LIVED IN THE
NEIGHBORHOOD.
I KNEW HER THROUGH NEIGHBORHOOD
EVENTS.
MY MOM KNEW HER.
SHE WAS A NICE WOMAN, A
KINDERGARTEN TEACHER.
I DIDN'T KNOW -- I KNOW HER
PERSONALLY.
>> -- I'VE KNOWN HIM SINCE I WAS
IN FIRST GRADE AND HE'S ALWAYS
BEEN THE WAY THAT I'VE DESCRIBED
HIM.
HE'S ALWAYS BEEN RESERVED BY IT
SO I DON'T KNOW IF THE DIVORCE
HAD IN ADDITION TO DO WITH THAT
AND I DON'T KNOW WHEN THEY
DIVORCED AND THAT COULD HAVE
CAUSED THAT AND MADE IT UNTIL I
WAS OLDER.
>> WHERE WERE YOU WHEN YOU THEIR
ABOUT THIS.
>>
>> I'M IN LONDON NOW STUDYING
HAIR FOR THIS SEMESTER AND I'LL
BE HOME ON THURSDAY, TO THIS.
I FOUND OUT FIRST, W IT WASN'T
AN OPTION AND I DIDN'T YOU HAVE
TO -- A TOWN YOU'VE GROWN UP IN,
MY WHO E WHOLE LIFE, I WAS
RAISED IN THAT ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
AND RACED IN THE SCHOOL SYSTEM
THERE AND FINDING OUT IT WAS
SOMEONE I KNEW ULTIMATELY WHO
HAD DONE ALL THIS IS JUST.
>>> AND AROUND UTAH, HOW WOULD
YOU DESCRIBE THAT?
>> A VERY KIND OF QUIET PLACE?
IT IT SFLUS NEVER HAPPENED?
>> RIGHT.
>> NO.
IT'S PRETTY BIG TOWN SPACE WISE.
WE SPAN OVER A VAST ARRAY OF
LAND.
EVERYONE REALLY CAME TOGETHER, I
THINK, THROUGH THIS AND ISRAEL
SUPPORTING EACH OTHER QUITE WELL
AND THAT'S THE ONE GOOD THING TO
COME OUT OF IT IF NOT ALL 123450
MIDDLE SCHOOL.
I DIDN'T REALLY HAVE ANY.
>> I NEVER NOTICED ANYTHING
SCARY OR VIOLENT OR ANYTHING
LIKE THAT.
I WOULD NEVER HAVE EXPECTED THAT
FROM HIM, I DON'T THINK.
JUST FROM SOMEONE WHO WENT UNDER
THE RADAR AND KEPT TO THEMSELVES
YOU WOULDN'T THINK OF THEM AS
DOING SOMETHING CRAZY LIKE THIS.
>> IT HAS TO BE A HELL OF A
SHOT.
I'M GLAD YOU JOINED US TO GIVE
US SOME PERSPECTIVE ON THE
CHARACTER OF THIS PERSON.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> OUR NEXT IS PSYCHOLOGY
OFFICE SHOOTER ADAM TO TALK
ABOUT THE GUNMAN.
COULD ONLY COM.
NEW NECTRESSE.
THE 100% NATURAL
NO-CALORIE SWEETENER
MADE FROM THE GOODNESS
OF FRUIT.
NEW NECTRESSE.
SWEETNESS NATURALLY.
BOPRODUCTIVITY UP, COSTS DOWN,
THTIME TO MARKET REDUCED...
THOSE ARE GOOD THINGS.
UPSTAIRS, THEY WILL SEE FANTASY.
NOT FANTASY... LOGISTICS.
UPS CAME IN, ANALYZED OUR SUPPLY
CHAIN, INVENTORY SYSTEMS...
UPS?
UPS.
NOT FANTASY?
WHO WOULD HAVE THOUGHT?
I DID.
WE DID, BOB. WE DID.
GOT IT.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
IF I MAY START WITH YOU, BRENDA.
LET'S START WITH YOU IF I MAY.
I HAVE BEEN INVOLVED IN MANY OF
THESE KINDS OF INCIDENTS AND
POSSIBLY NOTHING AS APPALLING AS
THIS.
THERE SEEMS TO BE A PATTERN WITH
AURORA AND THE SHOPPING MALL
SHOOTING LAST WEEK.
YOUNG MEN IN THEIR EARLY 20s
SUDDENLY FLIPPING AND GETTING
AHOLD OF WEAPONS AND CAUSING
OUTRAGES.
WHAT IS DRIVING THEM?
WHAT IS THE POSSIBLE BACKGROUND
TO WHAT IS GOING ON HERE?
>> WORKING ON A LOT OF THESE
CASES THERE A NUMBER OF
DIFFERENT CAUSES THAT CAN BE
DIVIDED INTO TWO BROAD
CATEGORIES.
ONE CATEGORY IS PEOPLE WHO HAVE
THAT TRAIT OF A LOSS OF EMPATHY
AND INABILITY TO CONNECT TO
OTHER PEOPLE AND A HISTORY OF
CRUELTY OR WHAT PEOPLE TALK
ABOUT AS SOCIOPATHS OR
ANTISOCIAL PERSONALITY.
AT THE OTHER END PEOPLE WITH
BRAIN DISORDERS AND SERIOUS
MENTAL ILLNESSES THAT ARE
UNTREATED OR BECAUSE OF WHAT'S
HAPPENING IN THEIR LIFE,
EXACERBATED BY STRESS.
IT SOUNDS LIKE THE LITTLE BIT
THAT IS COMING OUT, WE ARE MORE
IN A DIRECTION THAT THIS IS
SOMEONE WITH A BRAIN DISORDER
AND OTHER PARTS OF THE STORY
THAT IT MAY TAKE YEARS TO
UNCOVER IT.
THERE IS NOTHING SUDDEN ABOUT
ANY OF THESE STORIES.
THAT'S THE HEADLINE FOR ME.
IT'S SUDDEN FOR US THAT THIS
HAPPENED.
AS YOU BEGIN TO UNDERSTAND THE
STORY, I ASSURE YOU THE WARNING
SIGNS WERE THERE.
NOT THAT THEY WERE IGNORED, BUT
THEY WERE NOT RECOGNIZED.
>> ARE PEOPLE LIKE THIS AS
LIKELY TO CARRY OUT WHAT THEY
END UP DOING IF THEY DIDN'T HAVE
EASY ACCESS TO FIREARMS?
>> LOOK, THERE IS NO QUESTION
THAT FIREARMS PLAY A ROLE.
I CAN TELL YOU FROM EXPERIENCE
IF SOMEBODY WANTS TO KILL A
NUMBER OF PEOPLE, THERE OTHER
WEAPONS OF DESTRUCTION AND WAYS
TO MAKE BOMBS AND AT LEAST ONE
CASE I WORKED ON.
FIREARMS ARE CERTAINLY AN
IMPORTANT PART OF THE PICTURE,
BUT UNDERSTANDING WHEN SOMEBODY
HAS A MENTAL ILLNESS IF IT
PLAYED A AND I DON'T KNOW THAT
IT HAS, BUT IT NEEDS TO BE
CAREFULLY CONSIDERED BEFORE
ALLOWING THAT PERSON TO HAVE A
FIREARM.
>> FRANK, YOU SPECIALIZE IN
TREATING POST TRAUMATIC STRESS
AND THE EFFECTS OF VIOLENCE.
A VERY PARTICULAR PROBLEM HERE
WITH SO MANY YOUNG PEOPLE AT THE
SCHOOL WHO HAVE LUCKILY
SURVIVED.
HAVING TO DEAL NOW WITH THE
HORROR OF LOSING POSSIBLE
FRIENDS AND PEOPLE THAT THEY
KNEW FROM THE SCHOOL AND
TEACHERS AND THE HEAD TEACHER
AND SO ON.
WHERE DO YOU START WITH TRYING
TO COUNSEL YOUNG CHILDREN WHEN
THIS KIND OF APPALLING THING
HAPPENS?
>> I THINK THE FIRST THING IS
HELPING THE PARENTS.
THE CHILDREN LOOK TO THEIR
PARENTS AND FOR THE PARENTS,
SOME OF THEM ARE STUNNED.
THEY ARE GRIEVING.
THEY LOST A PRECIOUS 6-YEAR-OLD.
FOR THE CHILDREN THEMSELVES,
SOMETIMES CHILDREN WHO GO
THROUGH THIS AND DO SURVIVE TAKE
A WHILE TO MAKE SENSE OUT OF IT.
THEY MAY REGRESS AND MOVE
BACKWARDS A YEAR OR TWO IN TERMS
OF THEIR NORMAL DEVELOPMENT.
SOME OF THEM WILL FIGURE OUT
YEARS LATER WHAT ACTUALLY
HAPPENED.
SOME ARE GOING TO DO RELATIVELY
WELL.
THEY WILL BE SADDER AND WISER IN
A WAY.
THE MOST IMPORTANT THING IS WHAT
I SEE HAPPENING RIGHT NOW.
THAT COMMUNITY IS COMING
TOGETHER.
PEOPLE ARE LOVING EACH OTHER.
THE PRESIDENT HAS COME TO REMIND
US THAT WE ARE A NATION WHO
CARES AND HE CAME AS A FATHER.
I AM A FATHER AND A GRANDFATHER.
I HAVE CALLED MY CHILDREN AND I
WANT TO KNOW HOW THEY ARE DOING
WITH THEIR CHILDREN.
AS WE COME TOGETHER, WE DO THE
BEST THAT WE CAN AT A SAD TIME
LIKE THIS.
>> I SUPPOSE THE BIG QUESTION IS
WHY WOULD THIS SHOOTER DO WHAT
HE DID?
GO TO A CLASSROOM AND MURDER SO
MANY YOUNG CHILDREN OF SUCH A
YOUNG TENDER AGE, POSSIBLY THE
CLASSROOM THAT HIS MOTHER WAS
ALREADY KILLED AT THEIR HOME.
CAN YOU TRY TO PIECE FROM YOUR
EXPERIENCE THE THOUGHT PROCESS
HERE?
WHY HE WOULD THEN HAVING KILLED
HIS MOTHER GO TO THE SCHOOL AND
DO WHAT HE DID?
>> I DON'T HAVE A CRYSTAL BALL
AND I HAVEN'T DIAGNOSED OR
ASSESSED HIM.
PEOPLE WITH MENTAL ILLNESS ARE
NOT MORE VIOLENT.
THAT'S NOT THE CASE.
SIMPLY NOT THE DATA WE HAVE.
IF INDEED MENTAL ILLNESS IS A
PART OF THIS, THERE IS A
PARTICULAR PATH THAT NEEDS TO BE
LOOKED AT.
ARE THEY DEPRESSED AND
SUICIDALLY DEPRESSED.
HIS ROOMMATE ALEX ISRAEL SAID HE
PREFERRED TO STAY ALONE.
A SYMPTOM OF ASPERGER'S AND
REPORT THAT CAME OUT WHICH MAY
OR MAY NOT BE TRUE, THERE IS A
CAPACITY FOR EMPATHY AND SOCIAL
CONNECTION THAT LEAVES THE
PERSON SUFFERING FOR THIS
CONDITION.
THEY ARE PRONE TO SERIOUS
DEPRESSION AND ANXIETY.
IF THEY ARE SUICIDALLY
DEPRESSED, WE DON'T KNOW ENOUGH.
WHAT I AM TRYING TO DO IN
AGREEING TO COME HERE IS TO ASK
PEOPLE TO DON'T RUSH TO JUDGMENT
ABOUT WHO THIS YOUNG MAN IS.
IF IT WAS MENTAL ILLNESS THAT
PLAYED A ROLE, IT'S AN
OPPORTUNITY FOR US TO DO BETTER.
>> THERE IS A SCHOOL THAT YOU
SHOULDN'T GIVE HIM ATTENTION AND
NAME HIM AND SO ON BECAUSE IT
BRINGS ATTENTION TO HIM.
HE'S DEAD SO HE WON'T BE ABLE TO
BASK IN THE APPALLING GLORY OF
WHAT HE DID, BUT SECONDLY THESE
YOUNG MEN.
>> YOU ARE MAKING THAT
ASSUMPTION.
WE DON'T KNOW THAT.
I SPEND MANY HOURS WITH MEN LIKE
THIS WHO KILLED DOZENS OF
PEOPLE.
THEY DON'T NECESSARILY WANT
GLORY.
THEY ARE SERIOUSLY ILL.
OTHERS WHO DO WANT GLORY.
YOU ARE RUSHING TO A PARTICULAR
INTERPRETATION OF THIS.
IT'S WAY TOO SOON TO KNOW.
>> SORRY.
>> I WOULD LIKE TO ENDORSE THAT
ALSO.
I KNOW FOR THE WHOLE COUNTRY, WE
REALLY WANT TO KNOW WHY THIS
HAPPENED.
WHEN YOU ARE A PARENT YOU CAN'T
STOP THINKING ABOUT THESE
QUESTIONS THAT YOU ARE ASKING.
WE HAVE TO BE VERY CAREFUL IN
ANSWERING THEM.
WHEN YOU MENTIONED THAT WE HAD
SEVERAL SIMILAR CASES RECENTLY,
YES, THESE WERE SIMILAR IN THAT
GUNS WERE USED AND THEY WERE
SPREE KILLINGS AND MASS
KILLINGS.
I CAN TELL YOU AS A MEDICAL
DOCTOR AND PSYCHIATRIST WHO
WORKED CLOSELY ON CASES, THERE
WERE DIFFERENT MOTIVES AND
MENTALITIES.
THERE PEOPLE WHO DON'T HAVE A
CONSCIOUS.
THEY TORTURE ANIMALS.
THEY HAVE NO BASIS IN THEIR MIND
FOR EMPATHY OR SYMPATHY.
THEY LEARN HOW TO FAKE IT.
ONE OF THE COLUMBINE KILLERS FIT
THAT PATTERN, BUT THE OTHER WAS
DIFFERENT.
HE WAS NOT A PSYCHOPATH.
IN THE CASE OF THE AURORA
SHOOTER, THE JURY IS NOT IN YET,
BUT I HAVE A FEELING WE WILL
FIND HE WAS ON THE VERGE OF
MAJOR MENTAL ILLNESS ABOUT
DELUSIONS AND HALLUCINATIONS.
ONE TIME IN MY LIFE I WAS
RESPONSIBLE FOR THE FEDERAL
PROGRAM OF MENTAL HEALTH
SERVICES IN AMERICA.
I HAVE TO ADMIT WE FAILED.
WE FAILED AMERICA IN PROTECTING
THE LIVES OF THE SERIOUSLY
MENTALLY ILL.
MOST OF WHAT THEY DO IS SUFFER
IN SILENCE.
THEIR FAMILIES WANT TO DO BETTER
BY THEM AND AS A COUNTRY WE HAVE
NOT STEPPED UP AND BEEN
SYMPATHETIC AND CARING AND
APPROPRIATE FOR THE SERIOUSLY
MENTALLY ILL.
>> AN EXTREMELY IMPORTANT POINT.
WHAT I WAS GOING TO SAY IS YOU
BOTH HAVE MADE EXTREMELY VALID
POINTS.
YOU HAVE THREE SUCCESSIVE
APPALLING MASS SHOOTINGS
INVOLVING YOUNG MEN IN THEIR 20s
WHERE THE BACKGROUND TO ALL OF
THEM WAS NOT DISSIMILAR.
THEY SEEM TO BE FAIRLY NORMAL
KIND OF SLIGHTLY OFF, BUT
NOTHING WITH ALARM BELLS.
THE POINT OF EXAMINING THEIR
CHARACTER IS THAT THERE MUST BE
A GOOD LIKELIHOOD THAT THERE
OTHERS LIKE THAT OUT THERE WHO
MAY BE CONSIDERING SIMILAR
ATROCITIES.
HOW DO PEOPLE WHO KNOW THESE
TYPES OF PEOPLE SPOT ANY WARNING
SIGNS?
>> PIERS --
>> LET ME START WITH THE DOCTOR.
>> I'M SORRY.
I HAVE THREE SMALL CHILDREN.
BEFORE THIS INTERVIEW THEY ASKED
ME WHAT I WAS DOING AND WE
TALKED ABOUT THIS FOR ABOUT AN
HOUR AND A HALF.
MY 9-YEAR-OLD GOT FRIGHTENED, HE
GOES TO ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
I EXPLAINED TO HIM THAT THESE
THINGS ARE EXCEEDINGLY RARE.
LET'S NOT FORGET, THIS IS
EXCEEDINGLY RARE.
JUST BECAUSE SOMETHING HAPPENED
IN THE LAST MONTH DOESN'T
STATISTICALLY MAKE IT A COMMON
OCCURRENCE.
LET'S BE CLEAR AND TELL OUR
CHILDREN THAT.
THIS IS AN OPPORTUNITY TO TURN
TRAGEDY INTO AN OPPORTUNITY TO
FIX SOME OF THE THINGS THAT ARE
TERRIBLY BROKEN IN OUR MENTAL
HEALTH CARE SYSTEM AND KNOW HOW
TO IDENTIFY PEOPLE AT RISK FOR
VIOLENCE.
IT'S ALL AT THE LEVEL OF STATE
FUNDING.
SORRY ABOUT GET GET INTO THE
SPECIFICS, BUT IT'S MENTAL
HEALTH CARE AND SCREENING OF NOT
ONLY YOUNG ADULTS AND CHILDREN
WHO OFFER A GOOD ASSESSMENT, WE
CAN IN FACT DO A MUCH BETTER JOB
OF NOT ONLY CARING FOR THE
PEOPLE AND IDENTIFY THOSE WHO
WOULD NEVER BE VIOLENT IF NOT
FOR A MENTAL ILLNESS.
THAT IS ONE BIT OF THE STORY.
THERE IS ANOTHER PART WHICH IS
WHAT I THINK THAT MOST PEOPLE
ARE MORE FAMILIAR WITH AND
INTERESTED IN BECAUSE OF MOVIES.
THE DIABOLICAL SOCIOPATH.
BOTH STORIES ARE TRUE, BUT BOTH
ARE ACTUALLY QUITE RARE.
>> THE FINAL WORD, MAKE IT BRIEF
IF YOU MAY.
>> AMERICA HAS MORE GUN DEATHS
THAN ANY OTHER ADVANCED NATION
IN THE WORLD.
WE HAVE LAWS THAT SAY IF YOU ARE
SERIOUSLY MENTALLY ILL, YOU
SHOULDN'T POSSESS A WEAPON AND
WE DON'T ENFORCE THE LAWS.
WE HAVE TO GET TOGETHER ACROSS
THIS DIVIDE AND NEED THE NRA TO
STEP UP AND SAY THEY BELIEVE IN
GUN SAFETY AND NOT JUST IN GUN
OWNERSHIP.
WE NEED POLITICIANS ON BOTH
SIDES OF THE AISLE TO TACKLE
THIS PROBLEM.
WE WILL HAVE MORE DEAD AMERICAN
CHILDREN.
>> THANK YOU BOTH VERY MUCH.
STILL AHEAD, WE WILL TALK TO
SURVIVORS OF ANOTHER SHOOTING,
BUT NEXT THE PUSH FOR MORE GUN
CONTROL AFTER THE TRAGEDY.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
>>> THESE NEIGHBORHOODS ARE OUR
NEIGHBORHOODS.
THESE CHILDREN ARE OUR CHILDREN.
WE ARE GOING TO HAVE TO COMING
TO AND TAKE MEANINGFUL ACTION TO
PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS
REGARDLESS OF THE TOLL PICKS.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA ON THE
SHOOTING.
THE MASSACRE IS RAISING NEW
QUESTIONS ABOUT THE ACCESS OF
GUNS IN AMERICA.
HE IS URGENTLY CALLING FOR MORE
GUN CONTROL.
A FORMER CHIEF ECONOMIST ON THE
SENTENCING COMMISSION ON MORE
GUNS, LESS CRIME.
THE PRESIDENT OF THE CAMPAIGN TO
PREVENT GUN VIOLENCE.
THE ATTORNEY FOR THE MICHIGAN
AND RESPONSIBLE GUN OWNERS.
LET'S START WITH YOU.
YOU WERE PRETTY OUTSPOKEN SAYING
THIS IS TIME TO BRING IN NEW GUN
CONTROL LAWS.
>> YES.
IF THIS DOESN'T WAKE US UP, I
DON'T KNOW WHAT WILL.
I WAS HEARTENED THAT THE
PRESIDENT SAID WE HAD TO TAKE
MEANINGFUL ACTION AND THE ONLY
THING HE CAN DO IS LEAD A
CRUSADE FOR REASONABLE GUN
CONTROL LEGISLATION IN CONGRESS.
THESE MASSACRES ARE TAKING PLACE
MORE AND MORE OFTEN.
WE SAW BAY THE WAY TODAY A
SIMILAR INCIDENT IN CHINA WHERE
A MAD MAN ATTACKED AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN CHINA WITH A KNIFE
WITH 22 INJURED CHILDREN.
NOT DEAD.
THAT'S THE DIFFERENCE.
IN THE UNITED STATES WE HAVE
9,000 PEOPLE KILLED WITH GUNS
LAST YEAR IN SIMILAR COUNTRIES
LIKE GERMANY, 170 AND CANADA
150.
THERE IS A REASON FOR THAT.
>> WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE TO SEE IN
TERMS OF SPECIFIC GUN CONTROL?
>> THERE A NUMBER OF PIECES OF
LEGISLATION WE HAVE BEEN
PUSHING.
NO REASONABLE GUN OWNER WHO IS A
SPORTSMAN CAN OBJECT TO BANS ON
ASSAULT WEAPONS MADE ONLY TO
KILL AS MANY HUMAN BEINGS AS
POSSIBLE LIKE IN A MILITARY
SITUATION.
NO ONE CAN OBJECT TO A BAN ON
THE SALE OF LARGE AMMUNITION
CLIPS SO YOU CAN'T RELOAD.
NO ONE CAN OBJECT TO
MICROSTAMPING OF CARD RIDGES TO
TRACE THE MURDER WEAPON.
NO ONE CAN OBJECT TO ELIMINATING
THE GUNSHOT EXCEPTION SO EVEN IF
YOU BUY A GUN AT A GUN SHOW,
THEY STILL HAVE TO CHECK YOUR
BACKGROUND TO MAKE SURE THEY ARE
NOT SELLING TO SOMEONE ON A
TERRORIST WATCH LIST OR MENTALLY
UNSTABLE PERSON OR A FELON.
THOSE ARES WE SHOULD DO.
>> WE HAD A HEATED DEBATE ON A
PREVIOUS INCIDENT.
TWO THINGS HAPPENED IN 1996.
ATHERE WAS A MASSACRE IN
TASMANIA IN WHICH 35 PEOPLE WERE
KILLED.
THE AUSTRALIANS WAS RIGHT WING
AND FRIENDS OF GEORGE W. BUSH
AND BROUGHT IN DRACONIAN LAWS
AFTER THAT.
HE BROUGHT IN RIFLES AND
SHOTGUNS.
AS A RESULT OF THE NEXT DECADE,
FIREARM HOMICIDE RATE FELL BY
59% AND SUICIDE RATE FELL BY
65%.
>> NOT TRUE.
>> IT IS TRUE.
>> NO, IT'S NOT.
IF YOU LOOK OVERTIME --
>> IT IS TRUE.
>> I'M TELLING YOU PEOPLE CAN
LOOK IT UP THEMSELVES.
WHAT YOU FIND IS FOR DECADES THE
MURDER RATE WAS FALLING IN
AUSTRALIA.
IT BASICALLY STOPPED FALLING.
IF YOU COMPARE THE AVERAGE O TWO
DECADES WHERE IT'S FALLING TO
WHAT IT WAS AFTERWARDS, IT MAKES
IT LOOK LIKE THE AVERAGE BEFORE
IS HIGHER THAN AFTERWARDS.
IF YOU LOOK ON A YEAR BY YEAR
BASIS, THERE WASN'T THAT FALL.
>> WHY DOES ADAM LANZA MOTHER
NEED TO HAVE THESE THREE
WEAPONS?
ER INCLUDING THE SEMI-AUTOMATIC?
>> CAN I FOLLOW-THROUGH ON THE
AUSTRALIAIA THING?
>> NO, WHY DOES SHE NEED TO HAVE
THESE THREE WEAPONS PERFORMED
INCLUDING THIS SEMI AUTOMATIC
BUSH MASTER.
WHY WOULD A WOMAN TEACHER AT A
KINDERGARTEN NEED THESE WOMEN
ONS IN HER HOME?
ALLOWING THEREFORE A CLEARLY
DERANGED SON TO TAKE THEM AND
COMMIT THIS ATROCITY?
>> WHATEVER THAT GUN LOOKS LIKE,
IT'S A SEMI AUTOMATIC RIFLE.
ANY HUNTING RIFLE IS SEMI
AUTOMATIC.
DOESN'T MEAN IT FUNCTIONS
DIFFERENTLY.
HE FIRED OVER 100 ROUNDS IN
SEVERAL MINUTES WITH THIS
APPARENTLY HARMLESS RIFLE.
>> GUNS MAKE IT EASY.
>> YOU ARE TRYING TO SAY IT'S AN
AVERAGE GUN.
HE FIRED OVER 100 ROUNDS AND
KILLED 20 CHILDREN.
20 CHILDREN BETWEEN 5 AND 10.
WHAT POINT DO YOU SAY WE GET IT?
IT'S TIME FOR CHANGE?
>> IT IS TIME.
>> TIME TO DO WHAT?
>> TO GET RID OF THE GUN LAWS
THAT CAUSE --
>> TO GET RID OF WHAT?
>> LOOK AT WHAT HAPPENED.
ALL THE ATTACK THIS IS YEAR
OCCURRED WHERE GUNS ARE BANNED.
LOOK AT THE AURORA SHOOTING.
>> WHAT THE HELL HAS THAT GOT TO
DO WITH IT?
SERIOUSLY.
WHAT HAS THAT GOT TO DO WITH IT?
>> YOU NEVER LETE EXPLAIN.
CAN I SAY SOMETHING?
>> IS IT A GUN-FREE ZONE.
>> LOOK AT THE MOVIE THEATER
ONE.
THERE WERE SEVEN MOVIE THEATERS
SHOWING THE MOVIE WITHIN A 20
MINUTE DRIVE OF WHERE THE KILLER
LIVED.
ONLY ONE OF THOSE BANNED GUNS.
HE DIDN'T GO TO THE MOVIE
THEATER CLOSEST TO HIS HOME.
OR WITH THE LARGEST SCREEN.
HE WENT TO THE ONE MOVIE THEATER
THAT BANNED GUNS.
IF YOU LOOK AT BANS GENERALLY,
YOU CAN'T POINT TO A PLACE,
CHICAGO, D.C. WHERE WE BAN GUNS
AND MURDER RATES AND VIOLENT
CRIMES WENT UP.
IN THE UK IN JAMAICA AND
IRELAND, ISLAND NATIONS THAT
BANNED GUNS, YOU CAN'T FIND A
PLACE WHERE MURDER RATES HAVE
GONE DOWN.
THEY HAVE GONE UP USUALLY BY
LARGE AMOUNTS.
>> YOU CANNOT FIND A PLACE --
>> LET ME BRING IN.
>> FIRST OF ALL, BASICALLY EVERY
STATISTIC THAT JOHN CITED IS
PURE BUNK IN TERMS OF THE FACT
THAT THE MORE GUNS EQUAL --
THAT'S TRUE.
THEY WERE GUN-FREE ZONES, BUT
ATTRIBUTING THAT TO THE FACT
THAT THIS VIOLENCE OCCURRED,
THAT'S WHERE I HAVE TO STEP IN.
LISTEN, MY BROTHER WAS SHOT IN A
SHOOTING ON TOP OF THE EMPIRE
STATE BUILDING WHICH WAS
CHAOTIC.
I KNOW FIRSTHAND I TALKED WITH
THE VICTIMS FROM THE AURORA
TRAGEDY.
TO A PERSON, THEY ALL SAY IF
THERE WERE ANOTHER PERSON ARMED,
IT WOULD HAVE LED TO MORE
CARNAGE.
EXCUSE ME.
I LET YOU TALK, LET ME FINISH.
LET ME FINISH.
IF EVERY ONE OF THE CASES THEY
SAY IF THERE WERE MORE GUNS, IT
WOULD HAVE ONLY LED TO MORE
CHAOS.
AT THE EMPIRE BUILDING SHOOTING
IN NEW YORK.
THERE WERE HIGHLY TRAINED
OFFICERS IN THE CHAOS AND EIGHT
OTHER PEOPLE SHOT AND EVERY ONE
WAS AN INNOCENT CIVILIAN AND
EVERY ONE WAS SHOT BY A LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICER.
>> WE HAVE THE ATTORNEY FOR THE
RESPONSIBLE GUN OWNERS.
YOU BELIEVE THAT THERE SHOULD BE
MORE GUNS IN SCHOOLS.
SNART?
>> I BELIEVE THOSE OF US WHO ARE
LICENSED TO CARRY ARE
RESPONSIBLE PEOPLE AND SHOULDN'T
BE PROHIBITED FROM CARRYING IN
SCHOOLS OR OTHER PLACES.
IN FACT, THE MICHIGAN
LEGISLATURE PASSED A BILL LAST
NIGHT AND SENT TO THE GOVERNMENT
FOR SIGNATURE A BILL THAT WOULD
ALLOW THOSE OF US WHO ARE
LICENSED TO TAKE MORE DAY OF
TRAINING INCLUDING RANGE TIME
AND BE ABLE TO CARRY IN THE
PLACES WHERE WE COULDN'T CARRY
BEFORE.
>> WHY ON EARTH WOULD YOU WANT
MORE GUNS IN SCHOOLS AFTER WHAT
HAPPENED TODAY?
>> HERE'S WHY, PIERS.
IF WE COULD SUDDENLY MAKE ALL
GUNS DISAPPEAR, I WOULD HAVE A
DIFFERENT POSITION.
I SPEND A LOT OF TIME THINKING
ABOUT THIS AND READING ABOUT
THIS.
I TEACH A CLASS CALLED GUN
CONTROL SEMINAR AND I GET A NEW
GROUP EVERY TIME AND WE DISCUSS
THIS IN DETAIL.
THE SIMPLE FACTS ARE GUNS EXIST.
THEY ARE ESSENTIALLY 1800s
TECHNOLOGY.
SEMI-AUTOMATICS WERE IN THE LATE
1800s.
THEY ARE EASY TO MAKE AND LAST
SEVERAL HUMAN LIFETIMES WITH
MINIMAL MAINTENANCE.
SINCE GUNS EXIST AND WE KNOW FOR
A EXACT THAT THE ONLY WAY TO
STOP AN EVIL PERSON LIKE THE
PERSON YOU WERE DISCUSSING
EARLIER IN THE SHOW IS TO SHOOT
THEM.
>> THIS IS EXACTLY THE ARGUMENT
I HAVE BEEN HEARING EVER SINCE I
JOINED CNN.
I JOINED ON AIR ABOUT A WEEK
AFTER GABBY GIFFORDS THE
CONGRESSWOMAN WAS SHOT IN THE
HEAD.
EVER SINCE THEN, WE HAVE THE
SIKH TEMPLE AND AURORA AND THE
SHOPPING MALL AND SO ON AND SO
ON.
THE ARGUMENT I KEEP HEARING IF
EVERYBODY WAS WAS ARMED, IT
WOULDN'T HAPPEN.
IT'S HOG WASH, ISN'T IT?
IF EVERYONE IN THAT MOVIE
THEATER HAD GUNS, MORE PEOPLE
WOULD HAVE BEEN KILLED IN THE
MAYHEM THAT ERUPTED.
>> THE PEOPLE THAT STOPPED THE
ATTACKS.
>>> CAN I JUST --
>> THE PROVE IN THE PUDDING.
YOU DON'T SEE OTHER SHOOTINGS AT
GUN SHOWS OR --
>> THEY HAVE REASONABLE LAWS AND
THEY HAVE 100 PEOPLE A YEAR NOT
9,000 OR 10,000 A YEAR.
>> LISTEN --
>> IT WAS LOWER BEFORE GUN
CONTROL.
>> THEY GOT THE GUN ZOEL.
>> ALMOST ZERO CRIME.
>> THE GUN CONTROL DOESN'T
CHANGE IT.
>> SCOTLAND IN 1996 THERE WAS A
SIMILAR SCHOOL SHOOTING.
JUST AN AWFUL SITUATION.
16 YOUNG CHILDREN KILLED EXACTLY
AS THEY WERE TODAY.
AS A RESULT OF THIS, THEY
BROUGHT IN A HAND GUN BAN.
162,000 HAND GUNS WERE HANDED
IN.
IT IS TIME FOR THIS.
>> LISTEN --
>> MURDER RATES WENT UP.
>> THERE ABOUT 35 MURDERS A
YEAR.
THERE 12,000 MURDERS A YEAR FROM
GUNS IN THIS COUNTRY.
WHEN ARE YOU GUYS GOING TO FOCUS
ON THAT AND STOP TELLING ME THE
ANSWER IS MORE GUNS.
IT IS NOT THE ANSWER.
>> AFTER THE BAN, IT WAS HIGHER
THAN IT WAS BEFORE THE BAN.
>> YOU WANT MORE GUNS AND NOT
LESS?
300 MILLION GUNS IN AMERICA IS
NOT ENOUGH FOR YOU?
HOW MANY MORE KIDS HAVE TO DIE
BEFORE YOU GUYS SAY WE WANT LESS
GUNS AND NOT MORE?
>> HE ASKED ME A QUESTION.
>> LET HIM ANSWER THE QUESTION.
>> IMUPSET THAT THE GUN CONTROL
LAWS YOU ARE PUSHING HAVE KILLED
PEOPLE.
>> THAT IS NON--Y IS SENSE.
NONSENSE.
AVERAGE OF 35 KILLINGS IN
BRITAIN A GLEER A PLACE OF
BANNED HAND GUNS.
HERE NO BANS AND 12,000 PEOPLE A
YEAR DIE FROM GUN MURDERS.
>> YOU HAVE TO UNDERSTAND YOU
BAN THEM --
>> I HAVE BEEN DEBATING THIS ALL
WEEK WITH THE SHOPPING MALL
SHOOTING AND MONTHS IF NOT TWO
YEARS.
I AM SO FRUSTRATED AND FURIOUS
FOR THESE KIDS WHO ARE BEING
BLOWN AWAY AGAIN WITH LEGALLY
ACQUIRED WEAPONS.
SOME BOY WHO HAS PROBLEMS TAKES
HIS MOTHER'S THREE WEAPONS
INCLUDING THIS RIDICULOUS
ASSAULT RIFLE AND GOES IN THE
SCHOOL AND KILLS THESE KIDS AND
YOU GUYS STILL WANT TO TELL ME
THE ANSWER IS MORE GUNS?
IT IS MADNESS!
>> HOW ELSE CAN YOU STOP SOMEONE
FROM SHOOTING PEOPLE.
WHAT ARE WE MOST ANGRY ABOUT?
EVERY POLL SHOWS BY MASSIVE
MAJORITIES AMERICANS AGREE WITH
WHAT YOU SAID.
YET WE HAVE A LOBBY.
THE LEADERSHIP WHO FUNCTION AS
LEADERS WHO ARE ENABLERS OF MASS
MURDER.
POLITICAL PEOPLE AND EVEN THOUGH
POLLING SHOWS THAT MOST NRA
MEMBERS WOULD SUPPORT REASONABLE
GUN CONTROLS, THEY COME IN AND
LIE AND SAY THEY WILL TAKE YOUR
GUNS AWAY AND STOP ANY
LEGISLATION TO PREVENT THAT.
>> LET'S TALK ABOUT ENABLING.
>> NOBODY NEEDS ONE OF THESE IN
THEIR HOME.
END OF STORY.
>> I HAVE TO SAY SOMETHING.
>> THE ENCOURAGING THING AND
WHAT YOU SHOULD TAKE INSPIRATION
BECAUSE WE ARE ALL FRUSTRATED
AND OUTRAGED.
THIS CONVERSATION AND WHAT THESE
GUYS ARE SAYING DOES NOT
REPRESENT WHAT THE AMERICAN
PUBLIC WANTS AND THE
CONVERSATION THAT THE AMERICAN
PUBLIC WANTS TO HAVE.
WE ARE ALL IN FAVOR OF THINGS
LIKE CRIMINAL BACKGROUND CHECKS.
74% OF NRA MEMBERS ARE AND MOST
GUN SALES DO NOT REQUIRE A
BACKGROUND CHECK.
THINGS THAT WE CAN DO.
>> IT'S NOT AS THEY TRY TO TELL
ME AN ANTI-AMERICAN THING TO SAY
I RESPECT THE SECOND AMENDMENT
AND I RESPECT THE RIGHT FOR A
FAMILY TO DEFEND THEMSELVES.
I DON'T RESPECT FAMILIES TO LOAD
THEIR HOMES WITH THESE SO A
DISTURBED KID CAN TAKE THEM.
WE ARE ENDING THE DEBATE FOR
NOW.
[ Female Announcer ] BORN
FROM THE SWEET MONK FRUIT,
SOMETHING THIS DELICIOUS
COULD ONLY COME FROM NATURE.
NEW NECTRESSE.
THE 100% NATURAL
NO-CALORIE SWEETENER
MADE FROM THE GOODNESS
OF FRUIT.
NEW NECTRESSE.
SWEETNESS NATURALLY.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Incredible 4G LTE
by HTC for $49.99.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
>> PLIF POLICE OFFICERS ESCORTED
CHILDREN OUTSIDE THE SCHOOL.
THE JEWISH COMMUNITY CENTER IN
CALIFORNIA, THERE WAS A
6-YEAR-OLD STUDENT AT JCC AND HE
WAS SHOT IN THE LEG AND HE JOINS
ME NOW.
THERE'S ANOTHER JCC SURVIVOR AND
HE SURVIVED THE TRAGEDY AURORA
AND KILLED IN THE TEDLY SHOOTING
AT THE EMPIRE STATE BUILDING.
>> I IMAGINE WITH ANY MASS
SHOOTING WHAT WERE YOUR
FEELINGS?
>> IT'S -- IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO
PUT WORDS TO WHAT I REALLY FEEL.
IT'S A MIXTURE OF SYMPATHY AND
DISGUST.
AND MY HEART GOES OUT TO THOSE
FAMILIES AND THERE ARE PEOPLE
WHO HAVE GONE THROUGH THE SAME
THING AND WHO UNDERSTAND WHAT
ARE YOU GOING THROUGH, AND
IMMEDIATELY WHAT I THOUGHT WAS
JUST THAT I WISH THAT THERE WAS
SOMETHING I COULD DO TO HELP
THEM.
BUT, YOU KNOW, IN REALITY, IT'S
A HELPLESS SITUATION.
>> MINDY, YOU SURVIVED WHAT
HAPPENED TO YOU.
WHEN YOU HEAR THE RAGING GUN
DEBATE, WHICH WILL BE
PARTICULARLY VOCIFEROUS IN LIGHT
OF THIS APPALLING ACT TODAY.
DO YOU THINK THAT TOUGHER LAWS
SHOULD BE BROUGHT IN TO TRY AND
DO SOMETHING ABOUT THIS?
>> YOU KNOW, I DO.
I THINK JOSH AND I AND EVERYONE
IN OUR COMMUNITY IN THIS WEIRD
FAMILY WE HAVE, SURVIVORS OF GUN
VIOLENCE, WISHES THE DAY AFTER
WHAT HAPPENED TO THEM, NOBODY
ELSE HAS TO GO THROUGH IT.
UNFORTUNATELY, 13.5 YEARS LATER,
WE'RE SITTING HERE WATCHING
THESE TRAGEDIES UNFOLD ON A
DAILY BASIS.
>> YOU WERE 16 AT THE TIME OF
THE SHOOTING.
OBVIOUSLY, A LOT OF KIDS AT THE
SCHOOL TODAY WILL BE MUCH
YOUNGER THAN THAT, AND THEY WILL
HAVE EITHER LOST FRIENDS OR
PEOPLE THEY KNEW AT THE SCHOOL
IT WILL BE VERY DIFFICULT FOR
THEM WHEN THEY HAVE TO GO BACK.
WHAT ADVICE WOULD YOU GIVE THEM?
WHAT IS THE BEST WAY TO TRY AND
DEAL WITH THIS?
BEST SERVED FOR THEIR PARENTS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
>> YOU KNOW, TO BE HONEST, IT'S
HEARTBREAKING.
BECAUSE THEY ARE NOT GOING TO
KNOW REALLY WHAT OR HOW TO FEEL
UNTIL FIVE, TEN YEARS FROM NOW,
WHEN IT ACTUALLY KEEPS HAUNTING
THEM AND NIGHTMARES AND FEARS
THAT KEEP COMING UP.
JOSH CAN SPEAK TO THAT HIMSELF,
HE WAS SIX YEARS OLD AT THE
TIME, AND, YOU KNOW, NOW HE'S IN
HIS 20s AND IT HAUNTS HIM EVERY
DAY.
I WAS 16, I KNEW WHY I WAS SHOT.
I KNEW SOMEBODY TRIED TO KILL
ME, AND EVERY DAY, MY ENTIRE
LIFE, I'M ALMOST 30 YEARS OLD,
I'M HAUNTED.
THERE IS NOTHING I CAN SAY TO
THEM THAT I AM SO, SO SORRY THEY
HAVE TO GO THROUGH THIS, AND I
REALLY TRULY HOPE SOMETHING WILL
BE DONE AFTER TODAY, BECAUSE WE
CANNOT STAND FOR THIS ANYMORE.
>> STEVEN BARTON, YOU SURVIVED
THE AURORA MASSACRE A FEW MONTHS
AGO, A HUGE OUTCRY THEN AND
PEOPLE PROMISED TO DO ALL SORTS
OF THINGS, POLITICIAN MOUTHS THE
USUAL RHETORIC, ABSOLUTELY
NOTHING HAPPENED, AND LO AND
BEHOLD, HERE WE ARE WITH AN EVEN
WORSE TRAGEDY.
MORE DEAD, AND THIS TIME, 20
YOUNG KIDS.
WHAT ARE YOUR VIEWS ABOUT THE
DEBATE THAT WILL NOW UNFOLD ON
THIS?
>> I MEAN, I THINK THE PRESIDENT
SAID WE NEED A MEANINGFUL ACTION
NOW, AND HE SAID THAT IN THE
PAST, AND SO I'LL BE WAITING FOR
THAT ACTION.
IT'S A SHAME THAT 20 CHILDREN
HAVE TO BE SLAIN FOR US TO EVEN
START TALKING ABOUT THIS.
BUT I REALLY THINK THAT THE
AMERICAN PUBLIC IS FED UP WITH
THE LACK OF CONVERSATION ON THIS
ISSUE.
>> AND THERE WILL BE MORE MASS
SHOOTINGS IN THE LAST FIVE OR
SIX YEARS AND IN THE PREVIOUS
FOUR DECADES IN TERMS OF THE
PARTICULARLY APPALLING ONES.
AND YET YOU KEEP BEING TOLD,
WELL, NOT AS BAD AS IT SEEMS.
THE SITUATION, BUT IT TRULY IS.
SINCE I'VE BEEN HERE, I'VE BEEN
UTTERLY HORRIFIED, WHY I GET SO
ANIMATED WHEN I DEBATE IT ON THE
SHOW.
I COME FROM A COUNTRY WHERE THIS
WOULD BE UNTHINKABLE.
MOVIE THEATERS, SHOPPING MALLS,
KINDERGARTEN CLASSROOMS WOULD BE
SHOT DOWN IN AN INDISCRIMINATE
WAY ON A BIMONTHLY BASIS.
I DON'T GET WHY AMERICANS AREN'T
FAR MORE ANGRY.
>> IT'S ONE THING FOR A
POLITICIAN TO TAKE ACTION, BUT
IT'S EQUALLY IMPORTANT THAT THE
AMERICAN PUBLIC DEMANDS THESE
REFORMS, THESE CHANGES, AND THE
POLLING IS CLEAR.
SUPPORT FOR COMMON SENSE GUN
REFORM.
82 PERCENT GUN OWNERS SUPPORT
UNIVERSAL BACKGROUND CHECKS.
IT'S A FAILURE OF THE SYSTEM WE
HAVEN'T ARRIVED AT THAT POINT
YET.
>> PAULA, YOUR BROTHER WAS
KILLED IN THE EMPIRE STATE
BUILDING SHOOTING.
YOU BELIEVE IN THE RIGHT TO OWN
A HANDGUN AND A REFERENDUM
WASN'T NEEDED.
>> I THINK TODAY A REFERENDUM IS
NEEDED.
AS A FATHER, INNOCENT CHILDREN,
I SEE THE HEART BREAK, WE HAVE
TO GO BACK TO THAT.
WE HAVE 20 FAMILIES, 26 FAMILIES
THAT ARE DEVASTATED RIGHT NOW,
WHILE WE'RE HAVING THIS DEBATE.
THAT'S SOMETHING WE HAVE TO
FOCUS ON.
THIS IS ABOUT GUN CONTROL, ABOUT
MENTAL ILLNESS AND A
COMBINATION.
IT'S GOT TO BE ALL GROUPS THAT
COME TOGETHER.
>> IT INCLUDES VIOLENT VIDEO
GAMES, HOLLYWOOD MOVIES.