ONCE AGAIN LIEUTENANT VANCE,
WITH THE STATE POLICE HERE IN
CONNECTICUT.
HE'S BEEN THE ONE WHO'S BEEN
UPDATING US ON EVERYTHING THAT'S
HAPPENING.
WE'LL BE LISTENING TO WHAT HE
HAS TO SAY, HOPEFULLY GETTING
MORE DETAILS ABOUT THE SHOOTER.
HOPEFULLY GETTING SOME MORE
DETAILS ABOUT THE NEXT STEPS IN
THEIR INVESTIGATION, LOTS OF
QUESTIONS OF WHY THIS MORNING.
RIGHT NOW WE'RE ON THE SCENE
PROVELY A HALF MILE BEHIND ME,
YOU GET TO THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
ARE WHERE THIS HAPPEN.
NOT ONLY WAS THE SCHOOL AN
ACTIVE CRIME SCENE AS WE'RE
TOLD, BUT THE TEMPORARY MORGUE
HAS BEEN DELIVERED HERE UP FROM
NEW YORK CITY TO HELP OUT IN THE
PROCESSING OF THE MORE THAN TWO
DOZEN BODIES THAT ARE THE
AFTERMATH OF THIS CRIME.
WE ALSO KNOW THAT THERE ARE
INVESTIGATIONS HAPPENING NEARBY
BECAUSE OF THE MOTHER OF THE
SHOOTER WAS KILLED AS WELL.
AND WE ALSO KNOW THAT THERE'S
INVESTIGATIONS INTO THE WEAPONRY
THAT WAS USED.
WE KNOW THREE WEAPONS WERE USED,
TWO PISTOLS AND ONE
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE.
SO WE CONTINUE TO FOLLOW THIS
STORY HERE.
AND WE -- WE WILL UPDATE YOU ON
THE LATEST.
WE KNOW MORE, TOO, ABOUT SOME OF
THE VICTIMS.
NICK VALENCIA HAS BEEN COVERING
THAT PART OF THE STORY FOR US.
POLICE HAVE A NEW STATEMENT
ABOUT THIS CRIME.
HE IS AT THE CENTER OF OUR
NEWS-GATHERING OPERATIONS IN
ATLANTA.
NICK, CAN YOU GIVE ME THE LATEST
ON THAT?
>> Reporter: YEAH, GOOD MORNING.
AS YOU MENTIONED, WE'RE STILL
WAITING AND STANDING BY FOR WHAT
WAS SCHEDULED TO BE AN 8:00 A.M.
PRESS CONFERENCE BY LOCAL
POLICE.
MEANWHILE, THEY'VE ISSUED THIS
PRESS RELEASE.
STATE POLICE HAS PUT OUT A
STATEMENT FURTHER CONFIRMING, IN
FACT, THE TIMELINE THAT WE'VE
BEEN REPORTING ALL MORNING.
THEY SAY THE FIRST CALL FROM
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
CAME IN AT ABOUT 9:30 THIS
MORNING.
NEWTON POLICE DEPARTMENT
IMMEDIATELY REQUESTED THE
ASSISTANCE OF STATE POLICE.
IN FACT, THEY KNEW RIGHT AWAY
THE TRAGEDY AND SCOPE AND
MAGNITUDE OF THE TRAGEDY THAT
THEY HAD ON THEIR HANDS.
UPON ARRIVAL, TROOPERS AND
OFFICERS, THE STATEMENT SAYS,
IMMEDIATELY ENTERED THE SCHOOL
WHERE THEY FOUND SEVERAL
STUDENTS AND STAFF, SOLEDAD,
SUFFERING FROM GUNSHOT WOUNDS AT
THE FRONT OF THE BUILDING.
18 CHILDREN, 18 CHILDREN WERE
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCENE.
TWO WERE TRANSPORTED TO
NEIGHBORING DANBURY HOSPITAL
WHERE THEY WERE PRONOUNCED DEAD
THERE.
AND AS WE'VE BEEN REPORTING THIS
MORNING, SIX ADULTS WERE ALSO
KILLED, 26 SOULS IN ALL PERISHED
YESTERDAY AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
ANOTHER DETAIL THAT WE'RE
LEARNING FROM THIS IS THAT EACH
FAMILY, SOLEDAD, EACH VICTIM'S
FAMILY HAS BEEN ASSIGNED A
TROOPER OR OFFICER.
THE STATEMENT READS, TO
ESTABLISH AND MAINTAIN AN OPEN
LINE OF COMMUNICATION.
THE PRESS RELEASE GOES ON TO
STATE THAT THE FAMILIES HAVE
REQUESTED THAT WE NOT CONTACT
THEM.
THEY'RE REQUESTING THAT WE NOT
CALL THEM, NO PRESS INTERVIEWS
FROM THE FAMILY WHICH PROBABLY
EXPLAINS A LITTLE ABOUT THE
DIFFICULTY THAT WE'VE HAD ALL
MORNING TRYING TO GET IN TOUCH
WITH SOME OF THOSE FAMILY
MEMBERS.
BUT THEY ALSO SAY IN THIS PRESS
RELEASE, A SECOND CRIME SCENE WE
KNOW NOW, THAT'S WHERE THE
SHOOTER'S MOTHER WAS KILLED AT A
SECOND CRIME SCENE THERE IN
SANDY HOOK, CONNECTICUT.
AGAIN JUST IN, THIS PRESS
RELEASE FROM STATE POLICE
FURTHER CONFIRMING THE TIMELINE
OF WHAT WE KNOW SO FAR ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED EARLY FRIDAY.
SOLEDAD?
>> Reporter: THE BODIES HAVE
BEEN MOVED TO THE MORGUE.
IT WAS ONE OF THE MORE
DISTURBING DETAILS THAT WE GOT
YESTERDAY IN THE PRESS
CONFERENCE WHEN WE WERE TALKING
TO LIEUTENANT VANCE, THE ONE
WHO'S BEEN GIVING US THE BULK OF
THE INFORMATION.
HE WAS TELLING US BECAUSE IT WAS
AN ACTIVE CRIME SCENE THAT ALL
THE BODIES WOULD REMAIN WHERE
THEY HAD FALLEN.
SO THAT IS A BIG STEP FORWARD I
GUESS IN THIS INVESTIGATION TO
AT LEAST HAVE THOSE BODIES MOVED
TO THE MORGUE AND HAVE THE NEXT
OF KIN NOTIFIED AND HAVE I GUESS
CONFIRMATION FOR PEOPLE WHO WERE
STILL WONDERING THE VERY WORST
ABOUT THEIR LOVED ONES.
NICK VALENCIA WITH AN UPDATE FOR
US THIS MORNING.
THANK YOU, WE APPRECIATE IT.
WE ALSO KNOW THAT IN THAT LATEST
RELEASE, THEY CONFIRMED WHAT
WE'RE CERTAIN TO KNOW.
OF COURSE WE'RE WAITING FOR THE
PRESS CONFERENCE.
THEY SAID THAT THEY WOULD BE
DOING THE PRESS CONFERENCE
SOMETIME AFTER 10:00 EASTERN
TIME.
SO OBVIOUSLY AS THE MINUTES TICK
BY, THEY'RE NOW WAITING TO SEE
WHEN THEY'LL DO THAT.
LOTS OF QUESTIONS REMAIN.
WE'RE HOPING THEY CAN ANSWER
SOME QUESTIONS IN THE UPCOMING
PRESS CONFERENCE.
WHY WOULD THE SHOOTER COME TO AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL?
IT MAKES NO SENSE, IT REALLY
DOES BOGGLE THE MIND.
IT'S HARD TO IMAGINE WHY ANYONE
WOULD TARGET SOME SMALL
CHILDREN.
IT IS HARD TO UNDERSTAND WHAT
THE PARENTS WERE GOING THROUGH
AS THEY GOT A ROBO CALL TELLING
THEM TO COME TO THE SCHOOL.
THE SCHOOL HAD BEEN LOCKED DOWN.
TELLING THEM THAT THERE HAD BEEN
A SHOOTING.
CANNOT PUT YOUR MIND AROUND WHAT
PARENTS WERE THINKING AS THEY
PULLED UP TO THE SCHOOL.
THEY WOULD SEE AMBULANCES
STREAMING IN, AS WELL.
AND THEY KNEW THAT IT WAS HERE
AND THAT IT WAS VERY, VERY BAD.
AND CAN'T EVEN THINK ABOUT WHAT
IT WOULD MEAN TO TELL YOUR
CHILDREN THAT THEIR PRINCIPAL
HAS BEEN SHOT AND KILLED, AND
THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST HAS BEEN
SHOT AND KILLED.
WANT TO PLAY A LITTLE BIT OF
THAT.
>> WHEN I SAW THOSE TEACHERS,
WHEN I FOUND THE TWO CHILDREN
AND -- WE'RE DEVASTATED AND
HEARTBROKEN FOR THE POOR
FAMILIES WHO DID NOT HAVE THAT
MOMENT IN THE FIRE HOUSE OF
FINDING THEIR CHILDREN.
CAN'T EVEN IMAGINE.
AND OUR PRAYERS -- THE ENTIRE
COMMUNITY'S HEARTBROKEN.
WHEN I SAW THE TEACHERS AND
LOCKED EYES WITH EACH OF THEM
SEPARATELY, I FOUND THE TWO
CHILDREN, IF I COULD GO BACK, I
WOULD -- I WOULD EMBRACE THEM
BECAUSE I HAD NO IDEA WHAT THEY
HAD GONE THROUGH.
BUT IT WAS -- IT WAS ACTUALLY
HANDLED VERY WELL BECAUSE I
CAN'T IMAGINE THE PANDEMONIUM
THAT WOULD HAVE BEEN GONE ON IN
THE FIRE HOUSE FROM THE PARENTS
SEARCHING FOR THEIR CHILDREN.
IF ANYBODY THERE HAD ANY IDEA OF
THE LEVEL OF WHAT HAD HAPPENED
YESTERDAY.
PEOPLE JUST SIMPLY DIDN'T KNOW
REALLY WHAT WAS GOING ON.
THEY JUST KNEW THAT THEIR
CHILDREN HAD BEEN IN A DANGEROUS
PLACE, AND THAT THEY -- THAT
THOSE THAT MADE IT TO THE FIRE
HOUSE WERE, THANK GOD, SAFE.
>> Reporter: WHAT WILL YOU TELL
YOUR SON WHO'S A FIRST GRADER?
WHAT WILL YOU TELL YOUR DAUGHTER
WHO'S A THIRD GRADER?
DO THEY HAVE ANY IDEA OF THE
SCOPE OF HOW BAD IT IS?
>> YOU KNOW, I THINK THEY DO
MORE THAN THEY'RE LETTING ON.
WE HAVEN'T SAID MUCH, IT'S --
THIS IS SHOCKING.
SO WE'RE -- THIS IS NEW TO US.
AND WE'RE DEFINITELY GOING TO
TALK TO COUNSELORS TODAY OVER AT
THE REED SCHOOL.
WE'RE GOING TO LIVE AT OUR
CHURCH AT ST. ROSE AND LEARN
WHAT TO SAY BEFORE WE SAY IT.
IT'S REALLY TRICKY.
AND FOR MY THIRD GRADER, LITTLE
BITS AND PIECES ARE COMING OUT
NOW.
>> Reporter: SOUNDS LIKE SHE'S
NOT TALKING AS MUCH ABOUT IT.
>> NO.
LITTLE THINGS ARE COMING OUT NOW
WHERE SHE -- SHE HEARD A LOT.
THEY ALL HEARD AND SAW THINGS
THAT OUR CHILDREN SHOULD NOT
HEAR OR SEE.
THEY KNOW THAT IT WAS A BAD MAN.
AND WE SAID WE'RE JUST COMING TO
TALK TO PEOPLE.
THEY WANT TO KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
AT SANDY HOOK.
THEY DON'T KNOW -- THEY DON'T
KNOW THAT THEY'VE LOST THEIR
FRIENDS, THEIR PRINCIPAL.
>> IT'S BECOME APPARENT THAT OUR
6-YEAR-OLD HAS LOST CLOSE
FRIEN
FRIENDS.
HE'S VERY UNAWARE OF THAT NOW.
WE DON'T KNOW EXACTLY HOW TO
APPROACH IT WITH HIM AT THIS
POINT.
WE'RE GUARDING HIM FROM THE TV.
WHEN THEY FELL ASLEEP LAST NIGHT
AND THE EXPERTS WOULD COME ON
THE TV TO DISCUSS HOW TO TALK TO
YOUR CHILDREN, WE WERE
ATTENTIVE, LET'S LISTEN OR WATCH
THIS.
AND WE REALIZED WATCHING IT, IT
HAD NOTHING TO DO WITH US, HAD
EVERYTHING TO DO WITH THE REST
OF THE COUNTRY WATCHING IT, BUT
NOT THE PEOPLE INVOLVED, THE
CHILDREN IN THE SCHOOL.
IT'S IMPORTANT FOR US TO, WE
REALIZE AS THIS GOES ON, THAT WE
NEED TO TAKE ADVANTAGE OF THE
COUNSELING.
>> Reporter: YEAH, MANY PEOPLE
-- SO MANY PEOPLE HAVE SENT
MESSAGES TO ME TO TELL PEOPLE
LIKE YOU AND THE PEOPLE WHO HAVE
LOST THEIR CHILDREN.
JUST HOW SORRY THEY FEEL FOR
THEM.
>> YEAH.
I MEAN, YOUR HEART -- THIS IS A
FEELING, IT IS UNSPEAKABLE.
IT IS LIKE REACHING INTO YOUR
INSIDES AND PULLING THEM OUT.
I MEAN, WHEN THINGS HAPPEN TO
YOUR CHILDREN AND TO OTHER
PEOPLE'S CHILDREN -- I CAN'T
LOOK AT MY CHILDREN'S FACES NOW
WITHOUT SEEING THE FACES OF
EVERY ONE OF THEIR SCHOOLMATES
AND ALL OF THEIR FRIENDS AND
EVERYTHING THAT THEY'RE DOING
RIGHT NOW OR SAYING OR TALKING
ABOUT CHRISTMAS.
I'M THINKING, YOUR FRIENDS
SHOULD ALL BE HERE.
AND IT'S JUST -- IT IS SUCH --
IT IS SO HEAVY, SO HEAVY ON YOUR
HEART.
>> Reporter: THE NATION FEELS
THAT WAY, TOO.
>> YEAH.
THE OUTPOURING OF LOVE HAS BEEN
TREMENDOUS.
I MEAN, PEOPLE ARE CALLING FROM
ALL OVER THE WORLD.
WE'RE GOING TO NEED THAT NOW.
WE'RE GOING TO ABSOLUTELY NEED
THAT TO BE THERE AS A COMMUNITY.
WE LOVE SANDY HOOK.
THIS IS SUCH A GREAT PLACE.
AND THE PEOPLE ARE WONDERFUL.
AND WE'RE JUST GOING TO HAVE TO
REALLY EMBRACE EACH OTHER AND
OPEN OUR HEARTS AND OPEN OUR
ARMS AND OPEN THE CHURCH DOORS
AND GET EVERYBODY PRAYING AND
TOGETH
TOGETHER.
I THINK THIS IS SOMETHING WE
WILL GET THROUGH.
I DON'T THINK THIS IS SOMETHING
WE WILL EVER, EVER GET OVER.
>> I WOULD LIKE -- I WOULD LIKE
ALSO TO SAY THAT WE ALWAYS FELT
BLESSED THAT OUR CHILDREN WERE
AT SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
IT WAS AN ABSOLUTELY BEAUTIFUL
SCHOOL, FANTASTIC EDUCATORS.
THE PRINCIPAL WHO, GOD BLESS
HER, LOFHE
HER, LOST HER LIFE WAS JUST A
VERY SPECIAL PERSON.
AND ALL THE PARENTS KNEW THAT.
SO IT'S A VERY -- IT'S SHOCKING
BEYOND BELIEF THAT THIS HAS
HAPPENED.
AND WE'RE JUST GRIEF STRICKEN.
HEARTBROKEN FOR THOSE FAMILIES.
>> Reporter: WE'RE GOING TO
CONTINUE TO TALK THROUGH TO SEE
PARENTS LIKE THE PHELPSES
THROUGHOUT THE DAY.
THEY ARE OBVIOUSLY STRUGGLING
WITH HOW TO DEAL WITH THIS ISSUE
AND THE KIND OF HELP AND
ASSISTANCE THAT THEY NEED, AT
THE SAME TIME BEING VERY
GRATEFUL FOR THE OUTPOURING OF
SUPPORT THAT THEY HAVE FELT HERE
IN NEWTOWN FROM ALL THE PEOPLE
AROUND THE COUNTRY AND AROUND
THE WORLD WHO HAVE BEEN MAKING
THEIR CONDOLENCES WELL KNOWN.
AND OF COURSE WE'RE ALSO GOING
TO KEEP TALKING ABOUT THE ISSUE
OF GUN CONTROL IN THE COUNTRY,
FOR THE SECOND DAY IN A ROLE.
WE'
-- IN A ROW.
WE'RE HEARING PRESIDENT OBAMA
CALL FOR MEANINGFUL ACTION.
IT'S UNCLEAR WHAT EXACTLY THAT
WOULD MEAN.
WHITE HOUSE CORRESPONDENT
BRIANNA KEILAR IS AT THE WHITE
HOUSE FOR US.
LAY OUT THERE FOR ME, YOU HAVE
POINTED OUT THAT THE PRESIDENT
HIMSELF HAS NOT DONE MUCH ON THE
ISSUE OF GUN CONTROL.
SO WHAT ARE THE EXPECTATIONS OF
WHAT MEANINGFUL ACTION COULD
SPECIFICALLY MEAN?
>> Reporter: WELL, GUN CONTROL
ADVOCATES, SOLEDAD, THINK THAT
IT SHOULD MEAN FURTHER GUN
LEGISLATION.
THEY WANT TO SEE ACTION TAKEN.
THE THING, THOUGH, IS IT'S
UNCLEAR EXACTLY WHAT PRESIDENT
OBAMA MEANS BY WHAT HE SAID
YESTERDAY IN THE BRIEFING ROOM,
AND HE REITERATED TODAY IN HIS
WEEKLY ADDRESS.
HE WANTS TO SEE MEANINGFUL
ACTION.
IF YOU GO BY HIS PAST, IN 2008
WHILE HE WAS CAMPAIGNING, HE
SAID HE WANTED TO SEE A RENEWAL
OF THE SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPON BAN.
THE ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN THAT
EXPIRED IN 2004.
AND THERE WERE A LOT OF TRIES IN
CONGRESS TO RENEW THAT TO NO
AVAIL.
HE PROMISED THAT.
OBVIOUSLY SOMETHING HE DIDN'T
DELIVER ON DURING HIS FIRST
TERM.
THE BRADY CAMPAIGN A COUPLE OF
YEARS AGO GIVING HIM AN "F" WHEN
IT COMES TO GUN CONTROL.
I WAS WITH HIM IN JULY IN NEW
ORLEANS WHERE HE SPOKE TO THE
NATIONAL URBAN LEAGUE A FEW DAYS
AFTER THE SHOOTING IN AURORA,
COLORADO.
HE TALKED ABOUT HOW TO DEAL WITH
GUNS.
HE TALKED ABOUT HAVING A
CONVERSATION.
AND SO WHEN YOU READ BETWEEN THE
LINES THERE, IT DIDN'T SEEM LIKE
THERE WAS A WHOLE LOT GOING ON
THERE CONCRETE.
THAT, OF COURSE, WAS AN ELECTION
YEAR, NOT A WHOLE LOT OF
APPETITE TO DO SOMETHING IN AN
ELECTION YEAR.
FRANKLY, WHEN IT COMES TO
CONGRESS, THERE OFTEN IS NOT AN
APPETITE TO DO SOMETHING ON GUN
CONTROL.
AND IT'S NOT JUST ABOUT
REPUBLICANS WHO TRADITIONALLY
ARE IN FAVOR OF GUN RIGHTS,
THERE ARE DEMOCRATS OPPOSED TO
GUN RIGHTS OPPOSED TO GUN
CONTROL, LEGISLATION THAT MAY
TIGHTEN RESTRICTIONS.
THAT'S EVEN THE CASE YOU MIGHT
SEE IN THE SENATE WHEN YOU'RE
TALKING ABOUT THE SENATE
MAJORITY LEADER, A DEMOCRAT,
HARRY REID, WHO COMES FROM
NEVADA.
WE DON'T ACTUALLY KNOW AT THIS
POINT EXACTLY WHAT MEANINGFUL
ACTION IS GOING TO MEAN.
THIS IS SOMETHING THAT WE'LL BE
ASKING QUESTIONS ABOUT, GETTING
ANSWERS TO IN THE COMING DAYS.
CERTAINLY GUN-CONTROL ADVOCATES
WANT TO SEE MORE LEGISLATION.
>> Reporter: A RESOUNDING NO
COMMENT ESSENTIALLY FROM THE NRA
WHICH IS A VERY, VERY POSSIBLE
LOBBYIST, PROBABLY ANOTHER
POWERFUL LOBBY LOCATED IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, THE
NATIONAL SPORT SHOOTING
ASSOCIATION, AS WELL.
BOTH COMING FORWARD TODAY WITH
-- WITH NO COMMENT BASICALLY.
BRIANNA KEILAR FOR US, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
SOME ACTION TO MY LEFT HERE
WHICH IS GIVING ME A SENSE THAT
MAYBE THIS PRESS CONFERENCE IS A
LITTLE BIT CLOSER TO GETTING
STARTED.
I'M SEEING FOLKS START TO RUN
ACROSS THIS PARKING LOT WHERE WE
ARE ALL KIND OF SET UP.
AND IT LOOKS TO ME LIKE THEY'RE
KNEELING DOWN WHICH IS MAKING ME
THINK THAT MAYBE WE'RE GOING TO
HEAR IN A MOMENT FROM LIEUTENANT
VANCE.
HE IS WITH THE STATE POLICE, AND
HE'S BEEN THE GUY WHO'S BEEN
DOING THE BULK OF THE UPDATING
ON THE SPECIFICS OF THE
AFTERMATH OF THIS TERRIBLE
SHOOTING.
NOW ONE OF THE THINGS THAT WE
KNOW ALREADY FROM A PRESS
RELEASE THAT THEY SENT OUT SORT
OF IN LIEU OF THIS 8:00 PRESS
CONFERENCE THAT NEVER HAPPENED,
THEY SAID THAT THE BODIES WERE
NOW OUT OF THE SCHOOL, THANK
GOD.
HAD BEEN MOVED TO A MORGUE.
WE KNOW THAT NEW YORK CITY HAD
SET UP A MOBILE MORGUE UNIT TO
COME AND HELP OUT IN THIS
TRAGEDY.
THE NEXT OF KIN WE WERE TOLD IN
THE PRESS RELEASE HAD ALREADY
BEEN NOTIFIED.
AND THAT A TROOPER WOULD BE
ASSIGNED TO EVERY FAMILY THAT
LOST SOMEONE IN ORDER TO
NAVIGATE I GUESS OVER THE NEXT
DAYS AND WEEKS AS THEY GRAPPLE
WITH THE AFTERMATH OF THIS
TERRIBLE TRAGEDY.
BUT THERE ARE MANY MORE
QUESTIONS PEOPLE HAVE.
FOR EXAMPLE, THE SHOOTER, 20
YEARS OLD, ADAM LANZA.
HIS MOTHER WAS ALSO KILLED AT A
LOCATION NOT FAR FROM HERE.
BUT BEYOND THAT, WE ACTUALLY
DON'T KNOW VERY MUCH ABOUT HIM.
WE'VE HAD SOME DESCRIPTIONS FROM
FRIENDS AND SCHOOLMATES, BUT IT
IS UNCLEAR EXACTLY WHAT COULD
POSSIBLY MOTIVATE HIM TO PULL
OFF SUCH A HEINOUS AND JUST
HORRIFYING CRIME.
WE WANT TO CHECK IN WITH MARY
SNOW, OUTSIDE THE SHOOTER'S HOME
THIS MORNING.
MARY, BEFORE I GO TO YOU, I WANT
TO WARN YOU, THERE'S A LOT OF
ACTION WHERE I AM.
I MIGHT BREAK AWAY FROM YOU IF
THE PRESS CONFERENCE STARTS.
WHAT UPDATES CAN YOU GIVE US
THIS MORNING, MARY?
>> Reporter: WELL, SOLEDAD,
UNLIKE YESTERDAY WHERE IT WAS A
VERY ACTIVE SCENE HERE, IT IS
MUCH QUIETER TODAY.
WE ARE OUTSIDE THE LANZA HOME.
YOU CAN'T SEE IT BEHIND ME
BECAUSE THE ROAD IS BLOCKED OFF,
IT'S A LITTLE --
>> Reporter: I'M GOING TO
INTERRUPT YOU THERE.
AND LET'S IN FACT HEAD OVER TO
THIS PRESS CONFERENCE.
LOOKS LIKE LIEUTENANT VANCE IS
BEGINNING TO SPEAK.
LET'S LISTEN IN.
>> THE PROGRESS THAT WE'VE MADE
IN THIS INVESTIGATION.
WITH ME IS THE CHIEF OF POLICE
IN NEWTOWN, THE FIELD OPERATIONS
COMMANDER OF THE STATE POLICE,
AND MY COUNTERPART HERE FROM
NEWTOWN POLICE DEPARTMENT.
AS YOU KNOW, THE VICTIMS HAVE
BEEN POSITIVELY IDENTIFIED BY
THE OFFICE OF THE CHIEF STATE'S
MEDICAL EXAMINER.
THEY'RE STILL IN THE PROCESS OF
DOING SOME OF THEIR WORK, AND AS
SOON AS THAT WORK IS COMPLETED,
WE WILL BE PREPARED TO RELEASE
IN WRITING TO YOU A FORMAL LIST
OF NAMES, BIRTHDATES, AND
INFORMATION.
THERE IS ONE -- THERE'S A COUPLE
MAJOR FACTORS.
NUMBER ONE, WHEN WE RELEASE THAT
LIST, AND WE WOULD ASK YOU AGAIN
AS WE DID YESTERDAY AT THE
REQUEST OF ALL OF THE FAMILY
MEMBERS, THEY HAVE ASKED FOR YOU
TO PLEASE RESPECT THEIR PRIVACY.
THEY'RE GOING THROUGH, AS I KNOW
YOU UNDERSTAND, A VERY DIFFICULT
AND TRYING TIME.
WE HAVE, IN FACT, THE JUSTICE OF
THE CHIEF AND THE COLONEL
REASSIGNED AND CONTINUE TO
ASSIGN A TROOPER TO THESE FOLKS
TO HELP TO MAINTAIN THAT
SOLITUDE.
SO AGAIN, I WOULD ASK YOU, I'M
PLEADING WITH YOU, AS YOU KNOW
THIS IS EXTREMELY HEARTBREAKING,
DIFFICULT THING FOR THESE FOLKS
TO ENDURE.
PLOOEZ PLEASE
PLEASE ABIDE BY THEIR REQUEST.
IN ADDITION TO THE TOWNSPEOPLE
IN THE TOWN OF NEWTOWN, A CRISIS
INTERVENTION TEAM FROM YALE NEW
HAVEN HOSPITAL HAS BEEN
ESTABLISHED IN THE COMMUNITY.
THEY CAN BE REACHED VIA
TELEPHONE.
THAT TELEPHONE NUMBER IS
203-270-4283.
AND AGAIN, THEY'RE OPEN, AND
THEY'RE AVAILABLE TO ANYONE IN
THE COMMUNITY WHO MAY HAVE THE
NEED TO DISCUSS, TO TALK, TO
TALK ABOUT THIS INCIDENT IN ITS
ENTIRETY.
I HAVE THE ABILITY TO TAKE SOME
QUESTIONS.
I JUST SIMPLY WANT YOU TO
UNDERSTAND THAT WE STILL HAVE
MAJOR CRIME DETECTIVES AND
NEWTOWN DETECTIVES WORKING AT
THE SCENE IN THE SCHOOL.
THAT IS NOT COMPLETED, THAT
PROBABLY WILL NOT BE COMPLETED
FOR AT LEAST ANOTHER DAY AND A
HALF TO TWO DAYS.
I'M PUTTING A TIME LIMIT ON IT.
IT COULD TAKE LONGER.
AS I'VE EXPLAINED, WE HAVE DONE
EVERYTHING WE NEED TO DO TO
LITERALLY PEEL BACK THE ONION
LAYER BY LAYER AND EXAMINE EVERY
CRACK AND CREVICE OF THAT
FACILITY.
AND THAT DOES NOT INCLUDE OR
EXCLUDE I SHOULD SAY THE OUTSIDE
OF THE BUILDING.
THE OUTSIDE OF THE BUILDING IS
ALSO PART OF THE CRIME SCENE.
EVERY SINGLE VEHICLE IN THAT
LOT.
SO IT'S GOING TO BE A LONG,
PAINSTAKING PROCESS.
WE ACTUALLY HAVE THREE TEAMS
NOW, THREE MAJOR CRIME TEAMS IN
THE COMMUNITY.
OUR LOCAL PARTNERS WITH WORKING
WITH US.
WE'LL MOVE THAT AND EXPEDITE
THAT ALONG AS QUICKLY AS
POSSIBLE.
WE HAD A MEETING THIS MORNING,
AND THAT WAS A DELAY WITH THE
SUPERINTENDENT OF SCHOOLS.
SHE WILL BE HOPEFULLY IN THE
NOT-TOO-DISTANT FUTURE UP HERE
TO TALK BRIEFLY ABOUT SOME OF
THE ISSUES THAT SHE HAS
ENCOUNTERED.
THE MINUTE THE MEDICAL EXAMINER
IS DONE, AND I MEAN THAT
INSERIAL, THE MINUTE HE IS DONE
HE IS COMING HERE, AND WE WILL
AGAIN PROVIDE ALL THE DETAILED
INFORMATION OR AS MUCH DETAILED
INFORMATION AS WE CAN RELATIVE
TO THE WORK THAT HIS OFFICE DID
BOTH OVERNIGHT AND CONTINUE TO
DO AS WE SPEAK.
AGAIN, AS FAR AS ACTUAL SPECIFIC
QUESTIONS, I'LL TAKE A FEW.
BUT I HAVE TO TELL YOU, THERE
ARE CERTAIN THINGS THAT ARE
SIMPLY CARDS THAT WE'RE HOLDING
CLOSE TO OUR CHEST IN THIS
INVESTIGATION UNTIL -- NO
NOTHING'S TAKEN OUT OF CONTEXT
AND WE HAVE CONTINUITY OF ALL
THE INFORMATION THAT WE PROVIDE.
YES, SIR?
>> THERE WERE REPORT THAT THERE
WERE OTHER GUNS OTHER THAN THE
ONES FOUND IN THE SCHOOL.
ARE THOSE REPORTS ACCURATE?
>> NO.
THAT'S NOT ACCURATE.
THE WEAPONRY THAT WAS RECOVERED
BY OUR INVESTIGATORS RECOVERED
IN CLOSE PROXIMITY OF THE
DECEASED.
AND AGAIN, WE'RE INVESTIGATING
THE HISTORY OF EACH AND EVERY
WEAPON.
AND WE WILL KNOW EVERY SINGLE
THING ABOUT THOSE WEAPONS, I
KNOW FOLLOWUP QUESTIONS ARE
LEGALLY REGISTERED, WHO ARE THE
OWNERS, SO ON, THAT'S BEING DONE
BY THE INVESTIGATORS ASSIGNED TO
THE TASK.
WE'RE, AGAIN, WE'RE GOING TO
ALLOW THE MEDICAL EXAMINER, WAIT
FOR THE MEDICAL EXAMINER TO COME
IN AND PROVIDE THE IDENTITIES OF
THE SHOOTER, OF ALL THE DECEASED
IN THIS INVESTIGATION.
>> HAVE YOU FOUND ANY WRITINGS,
EMAILS, ANY MESSAGES THAT YOU
MIGHT VIEW AS TO WHAT IS GOING
--
>> THAT'S A FAIR, GOOD QUESTION.
THE ANSWER I CAN GIVE YOU ON
THAT IS THAT OUR INVESTIGATORS
AT THE CRIME SCENE, THE SCHOOL
AND SECONDARILY AT THE SECONDARY
CRIME SCENE THAT WE DISCUSSED
WHERE THE FEMALE WAS LOCATED
DECEASED DID PRODUCE SOME VERY
-- VERY GOOD EVIDENCE IN THIS
INVESTIGATION, THAT OUR
INVESTIGATORS WILL BE ABLE TO
USE IN HOPEFULLY PAINTING THE
COMPLETE PICTURE AS TO HOW AND
MORE IMPORTANTLY WHY THIS
OCCURRED.
>> CAN YOU CHARACTERIZE THIS
TYPE OF EVIDENCE --
>> WE'RE NOT GOING TO NAME THE
EVIDENCE.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO TALK ABOUT
THE EVIDENCE.
SIMPLY STATED, IT'S PART AND
PARCEL TO THE INVESTIGATION.
I DON'T WANT TO TAKE IT OUT OF
THE CONTEXT OF WHAT'S BEING
DONE.
>> CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT
SHATTERED GLASS --
>> WE HAVE ESTABLISHED THE POINT
OF ENTRY.
I CAN TELL YOU IT'S BELIEVED HE
WAS NOT VOLUNTARILY LET INTO THE
SCHOOL AT ALL.
THAT HE FORCED HIS WAY INTO THE
SCHOOL.
THAT'S AS FAR AS WE CAN GO ON
THAT.
>> ARE THERE BROKEN WINDOWS AT
THE SCHOOL?
>> WHAT?
>> BROKEN WINDOWS?
>> YEAH.
FRANKLY, THAT'S SOMETHING,
AGAIN, IF YOU TAKE IT OUT OF
CONTEXT, IT SOUNDS SUSPICIOUS.
BUT AS THE RESCUE CREWS ARRIVED,
THE ACTIVE SHOOTING TEAMS
ENTERED THE SCHOOL, THEY ENTERED
THE SCHOOL FROM SEVERAL
DIFFERENT POINTS.
AND IT NECESSITATED THEIR WAY IN
TO GAIN ACCESS TO PERFORM THE
RESCUE AND TO SAVE AS MANY
STUDENTS AND FACULTY AS THEY
COULD.
HENCE, LAW ENFORCEMENT BROKE
MANY WINDOWS.
>> THE OTHER CRIME SCENE --
>> YEAH, THE SECONDARY CRIME
SCENE AS I TOLD YOU WAS A CRIME
SCENE THAT WAS DISCOVERED
PURSUANT TO THE INVESTIGATION.
ONCE WE HAD THE TENTATIVE
IDENTIFICATION ON THE SUSPECT,
WE BEGAN DOING A GREAT DEAL OF
WORK, AGAIN, PEELING BACK THE
ONION.
EVERYTHING WE COULD FIND OUT
ABOUT THE SUSPECT INCLUDING AND
NOT LIMITED TO RELATIVES,
FRIENDS, CO-WORKERS, FORMER
STUDENTS, LOCATION OF RESIDENTS,
AND ALL THOSE AREAS HAD TO BE --
PEOPLE HAD TO BE INTERVIEWED AND
THE AREAS HAD TO BE EXAMINED.
HENCE, THAT CAUSED US TO
DISCOVER THE SECONDARY CRIME
SCENE WHICH WAS A PRIVATE
RESIDENCE WITH THE SOLE FEMALE
DECEASED.
>> WAS THERE PROVIDED A MOTIVE
OR EXPLANATION AS TO WHY --
>> TO BE DETERMINED.
THE DETECTIVES WILL ANALYZE
EVERYTHING AND PUT A COMPLETE
PICTURE TOGETHER OF THE EVIDENCE
THAT THEY DID OBTAIN.
WE'RE HOPEFUL, WE'RE HOPEFUL
THAT TELL PAINT A COMPLETE
PICTURE AS TO HOW AND WHY THIS
ENTIRE INCIDENT, UNFORTUNATE
INCIDENT OCCURRED.
>> AT THE CRIME SCENE, DID YOU
FIND A MAN OR WOMAN?
WILL.
>> I'M SORRY?
>> THERE WAS ONE WOMAN WHO WAS
SHOT AND SURVIVED.
HOW IS SHE?
>> SHE IS DOING FINE.
SHE'S -- SHE HAS BEEN TREATED,
AND SHE'LL BE INSTRUMENTAL IN
THIS INVESTIGATION, AS I'M SURE
YOU CAN UNDERSTAND.
[ INAUDIBLE ]
>> THAT I DON'T KNOW.
>> THE SHOOTER IN THIS CASE
APPEARED TO BREAK INTO THE
SCHOOL --
>> FORCED HIS WAY INTO THE
SCHOOL.
THAT WOULD BE ACCURATE,
ACCORDING TO INVESTIGATORS.
YES.
>> AND DOES IT APPEAR HE USED TO
WEAPONS TO BREAK HIS WAY --
>> I DON'T WANT TO BE TOO
SPECIFIC BECAUSE FRANKLY I DON'T
KNOW.
SO I WOULD SIMPLY -- I'VE BEEN
INFORMED THAT IT WAS FORCIBLY
ENTERED AND WAS NOT ALLOWED TO
ENTER IF YOU WILL.
WHAT I'D LIKE TO DO IS -- IS I'D
LIKE TO GET THE NEXT PORTION IF
YOU WILL TODAY -- I DON'T WANT
TO KEEP YOU HERE ALL DAY.
I'M GOING TO TRY IT AND DO THIS
AS EXPEDITIOUSLY AS I CAN AND
GET AS MUCH INFORMATION TO YOU.
WE'D LIKE TO GET THE
SUPERINTENDENT, DEFINITELY WANTS
TO COME UP WITH TOWN LEADERS TO
DISCUSS CERTAIN AREAS OF HER
RESPONSIBILITY.
THEN WE CERTAINLY WANT TO GET
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER UP HERE.
AGAIN, WE'LL DO THAT AS QUICKLY
AS WE CAN SO WE CAN GET THE LIST
OF I.D.s AND INFORMATION TO YOU.
FOR ANY OF YOU WHO ARE NEW, THE
LIEUTENANT AND I PUT TOGETHER A
WRITTEN PRESS RELEASE.
WE'LL PROVIDE THOSE TO YOU AT MY
VEHICLE.
PLEASE DON'T RUSH MY VEHICLE.
WE HAVE -- WE SHOULD HAVE ENOUGH
FOR EVERYONE.
AND IF NOT WE'LL BRING MORE THE
NEXT TIME WE COME UP.
IT LAYS OUT THE BAKE DETAISIC DF
EVERYTHING LEADING UP TO TODAY.
ALL RIGHT.
WE WILL TRY -- I DON'T WANT TO
GIVE YOU A TIME, BUT WE'LL TRY
TO BE BACK I'LL SAY WITHIN THE
HOUR.
I'LL MAKE NOTIFICATION SOME OF
YOU THAT I CAN THAT WE'RE ON THE
WAY.
ALL RIGHT?
YES, SIR, ONE QUESTION.
>> THE MOTHER OF THE --
[ INAUDIBLE ]
>> YOU HAVE TO UNDERSTAND THAT
AFTER THE SHOOTING WE DID A
COMPLETE AND THOROUGH SEARCH OF
THE AREA, THE NEIGHBORHOOD, WITH
OUR LOCAL PARTNERS.
EVERYTHING WAS EXAMINED.
IF WE FOUND ANYONE THAT WAS IN
THE WOODS CUTTING WOOD THERE
WOULD BE -- THEY WOULD BE
DETAINED PENDING THE
INVESTIGATION.
THERE WERE NO OTHER ARREST
ASSOCIATED WITH THIS
INVESTIGATION THAT OCCURRED.
OKAY?
[ ALL TALKING AT ONCE ]
>> I WOULD HAVE YOU ADDRESS THAT
WITH THE SUPERINTENDENT OF
SCHOOLS, OKAY?
WE CAN -- SHE CAN GIVE YOU THAT
ANSWER.
WE WILL BE BACK.
I NEED TO GET -- IF I DON'T GET
HERE, WE'LL BE HERE QUITE SOME
TIME.
I KNOW YOU HAVE A LOT OF
QUESTIONS.
I THINK THE PEOPLE THAT WE'RE
BRINGING TO SPEAK TO YOU CAN
ANSWER THESE QUESTIONS AND PUT A
LOT OF -- TAKE A LOT OF THE
MYSTERY OUT OF WHAT WE'VE BEEN
DEALING WITH FOR THE LAST 24
HOURS.
OKAY.
WE WILL BE BACK.
>> Reporter: WELCOME BACK.
YOU'VE BEEN LISTENING TO A PRESS
CONFERENCE HELD BY LIEUTENANT
VANCE WITH THE STATE POLICE.
NOT A LOT TO UPDATE FOLKS ON.
THEY HAD SENT OUT A WRITTEN
STATEMENT AS WELL, IT WAS
CONSISTENT.
SAID A COUPLE OF THINGS.
HE WAS JOINED BY THE CHIEF OF
POLICE FROM THE TOWN HERE IN
NEWTON, CONNECTICUT.
ALSO A LIEUTENANT WITH THE
POLICE DEPARTMENT.
HE SAID AS SOON AS THE LIST OF
DECEASED IS, IN FACT, COMPLETED
THAT HE WOULD MAKE THAT PUBLIC.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER WOULD BE
CHARGED WITH THAT.
THAT ALL THE FAMILY MEMBERS WHO
HAVE LOST SOMEONE HAVE -- HAVE
BEEN UNITED IN SAYING THEY WOULD
LIKE EVERYONE TO RESPECT THEIR
PRIVACY.
AND TO THAT END, HE HAS ASSIGNED
A TROOPER TO EACH OF THE
FAMILIES.
AND HE CALLED THAT TO HELP
MAINTAIN THE SOLITUDE.
MEANING THAT THERE WILL BE A
BARRIER TO KEEP PEOPLE FROM
GETTING TO THOSE FAMILIES, TO
GIVE THEM SOME TIME AND GIVE
THEM SOME DISTANCE AND RESPECT
THEIR PRIVACY.
AND HE RE-EMPHASIZED THAT.
HE SAID, WE'RE ASKING AND I AM
PLEADING WITH YOU, TALKING TO
THE LARGE MEMBER OF PRESS THAT'S
BEEN GATHERED HERE.
ASKING AND PLEADING TO PLEASE
RESPECT THEIR PRIVACY, WHAT THEY
HAVE LOST IS JUST UNIMAGINABLE
AT THIS POINT.
HE SAID THAT A CRISIS
INTERVENTION TEAM FROM YALE NEW
HAVEN HOSPITAL WAS ON THE SCENE.
THEY'D BE AVAILABLE BY PHONE TO
ANYBODY WHO HAD A QUESTION OR
WANTED SOME SGIENS, W SGIE-- SO
GUIDANCE IN THE COMMUNITY.
DETECTIVES ARE ON THE SCENE OF
THE SCHOOL.
HE SAID IT COULD TAKE A DAY, IT
COULD TAKE AS LONG AS TWO DAYS.
THEY'RE GOING TO PEEL BACK THE
ONION, HIS QUOTE, TO TRY TO
INVESTIGATE EVERY CRACK AND
CREVICE AND REALLY FIGURE OUT
WHAT HAPPENED AND THE ORDER IN
WHICH THINGS HAD HAPPENED IN
THAT TEN-MINUTE WINDOW WHEN THE
SHOOTINGS HAPPENED.
OUTSIDE OF THE BUILDING, HE SAID
IT WAS ALSO PART OF THAT CRIME
SCENE.
THERE ARE THREE CRIME TEAMS, HE
SAID.
AND HE -- ESSENTIALLY ENDED BY
SAYING INVESTIGATORS WOULD
EVENTUALLY HAVE A VERY FULL
PICTURE OF HOW AND WHY THIS
OCCURRED.
THE HOW AND WHY WHICH, OF
COURSE, I THINK ARE THE
QUESTIONS THAT EVERYBODY'S
REALLY BEEN TRYING TO
UNDERSTAND.
HE SAID THEY WANT TO TALK TO
RELATIVES AND FRIENDS AND
CO-WORKERS AND FORMER CLASSMATES
OF THE SHOOTER'S.
THAT THE WOMAN WHO WAS, WE KNOW
WAS INJURED AND WHO HAD BEEN AT
ONE POINT IN THE ROOM WITH THE
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST AND THE
PRINCIPAL, THEY WERE HAVING A
MEETING ABOUT A STUDENT THAT
MORNING.
SHE ENDED UP BEING SHOT IN THE
FOOT I BELIEVE AND ALSO THE ARM.
BUT THAT SHE WAS GOING TO BE
INSTRUMENTAL IN PIECING TOGETHER
WHAT HAD HAPPENED IN THIS
INVESTIGATION.
AND WITH THAT, HE ENDED WHAT WAS
A SHORT PRESS CONFERENCE.
HE SAID THE SUPERINTENDENT AND
TOWN LEADERS ARE GOING WANT TO
TALK TO FOLKS.
AND ALSO THE MEDICAL EXAMINER
WOULD BE SOMEONE THAT WE WOULD
BE HEARING FROM AS SOON AS THEY
FINISHED THE IDENTIFICATION
PROCESS.
THEY WOULD BE ABLE TO UPDATE US
ON SOME MORE INFORMATION.
SO THAT'S WHERE IT STANDS RIGHT
NOW IN TERMS OF THE
INVESTIGATION.
BUT I'D GO BACK TO THE HOW AND
THE WHY.
I THINK SANJAY GUPTA IS JOINING
ME NOW.
THAT IS ALWAYS THE QUESTION FOR
THOSE OF US WHO COVER THESE
THINGS AND THOSE OF US WHO WATCH
IT ON TV AND PEOPLE IN TOWN,
TOO, CERTAINLY, PEOPLE WHO LOST
PEOPLE.
THE WHY BEHIND IT.
THERE HAS BEEN -- IS THERE A
CONNECTIONTIVE THREAD WHEN IT
COMES TO THESE MASS SHOOTINGS?
ARE THERE THINGS THAT HAPPEN IN
MASS SHOOTINGS THAT DEAL WITH
MENTAL STABILITY?
>> OFTENTIMES THERE ARE.
BUT OFTEN TIMES I KEEP HEARING,
AND I'VE TALKED TO PEOPLE AS YOU
HAVE OVER THE YEARS, A LOT OF
TIMES THE ANSWER IS UNKNOWABLE.
IT'S NOT SATISFYING, PEOPLE WANT
TO KNOW THE ANSWER TO THESE
QUESTIONS.
BUT SOMETIMES WE JUST NEVER CAN
KNOW FOR SURE.
EVEN AFTER THE INVESTIGATION IS
DONE, THE PEOPLE THAT ARE
CLOSEST TO THE PERSON INVOLVED
HERE, YOU STILL DON'T HAVE A
VERY SATISFYING ANSWER.
AND I JUST SAY THAT BECAUSE I
THINK IT'S SOMETHING THAT PEOPLE
MAY NEED TO BE PREPARED FOR.
OVER THE NEXT COUPLE OF DAYS, IT
MAY NOT COME BACK A DEFINITIVE
REASON.
ALL SORTS OF SPECULATION AS YOU
KNOW TO WHAT PEOPLE ARE SAYING
ABOUT THIS.
I DON'T KNOW THAT WE KNOW ANY OF
THAT FOR SURE, AND WE MAY NEVER.
>> Reporter: WE KNOW THAT A
FAMILY MEMBER TOLD INVESTIGATORS
THAT THE SHOOTER HAD SOME TYPE
OF AUTISM.
I THINK A PHRASE THEY USED.
AND AS I'VE TOLD YOU A BUNCH OF
TIMES, MY NEPHEW'S AUTISTIC.
I KNOW A LITTLE ABOUT AUTISM.
I HAD NEVER SEEN ANY CONNECTION
BETWEEN AUTISM AND VIOLENT
BEHAVIOR.
IS THERE A CONNECTION BETWEEN
AUTISM AND ANY VIOLENT BEHAVIOR?
VIOLENT BEHAVIOR AND ANY OTHER
MENTAL ILLNESS -- I SHOULD SAY
OF MENTAL ILLNESS SINCE AUTISM
IS NOT A MENTAL ILLNESS.
>> RIGHT.
AUTISM IS NOT A MENTAL ILLNESS,
IT'S NOT A PERSONALITY DISORDER
AS SOME PEOPLE HAVE SUGGESTED.
THERE'S NO EVIDENCE TO SUGGEST
THAT THERE'S A LINK BETWEEN
AUTISM OR ANYTHING ON THE AUTISM
SPECTRUM AND PLANNED VIOLENCE.
THERE CAN BE REACTIVE VIOLENCE,
CALL THEM VIOLENT OUTBUSTS.
THAT THEIR CAN BE LIMITED --
SINCE WE SPOKE I LOOKED UP SOME
MORE RESEARCH ON THAT.
THERE WAS ONE STUDY THAT SAID
OUT OF 132 PEOPLE WHO HAD
AUTISM, THERE WERE THREE
DEMOCRAT THAT DEMONSTRATED
EVIDENCE OF VIOLENCE.
AGAIN, THAT WAS REACTIVE
VIOLENCE, NOT PLANNED VIOLENCE
AS SEEMS TO HAVE OCCURRED HERE.
>> Reporter: SO WHAT -- WHAT
WILL THE RECOVERY PROCESS BE FOR
PEOPLE?
I MEAN, EVERY PARENT I TALKED TO
AND NOW IN THE, YOU KNOW, 18
HOURS WE'VE BEEN HERE ON THE
SCENE, THEY'RE TRAUMATIZED.
THE PARENTS ARE TRAUMATIZED.
SOME HAD BROUGHT THEIR KIDS WITH
THEM, AND THE CHILDREN ARE
CLEARLY TRAUMATIZED.
AND THEY DON'T REALLY KNOW WHAT
TO DO.
>> YOU KNOW, I THINK IF THERE'S
ANY GOOD NEWS IN THIS, THAT IS
LOOKING THROUGHOUT HISTORY AND
EVERYTHING IS OBVIOUSLY
UNPRECEDENTED HERE, BUT
TYPICALLY IT IS A MOURNING
PROCESS THAT WILL LAST.
BUT IT IS SHORT-LIVED AND MAYBE
EVEN MORE SHORT-LIVED FOR THE
CHILDREN AS COMPARED TO THEIR
PARENTS.
CHILDREN TEND TO BE MORE
RESILIENT HERE.
I THINK OBVIOUSLY TALKING ABOUT
THIS, BUT ALSO RESTORING SOME
SORT OF NORMALCY TO THEIR LIVES.
AND YOU KNOW, WE SAY THAT ALL
THE TIME, BUT IT MAKES A HUGE
DIFFERENCE TO ACTUALLY GO BACK
TO SOME SORT OF NORMAL PATTERN.
IF YOU HAD SOCCER PRACTICE ON
SATURDAY, TO DO THAT PRACTICE.
PIANO LESSONS TOMORROW, THE SAME
THING.
>> Reporter: HOW POSSIBLY DO YOU
REOPEN A SCHOOL WHERE CHILDREN
WERE HIDING INSIDE THEIR CUBBIES
HOPING NOT TO GET SHOT?
I KNOW THAT EVENTUALLY COLUMBINE
WAS REOPENED, RIGHT?
THERE WAS A SIMILAR HORRIFIC
EXPERIENCE.
AND PEOPLE DID EVENTUALLY GO
BACK.
BUT I JUST CAN'T WRAP MY MIND
AROUND THAT.
>> I DON'T KNOW IF IT NEEDS TO
BE COMMEMORATED IN ONE WAY AND
ACKNOWLEDGED.
I THINK A COMPLETE TRANSPARENCY
SEEMS TO BE KEY HERE, NOT TRYING
TO HIDE THESE THINGS.
MAKING SURE THAT PEOPLE KNOW
THAT IN FACT THIS DID HAPPEN
HERE, BUT THAT -- PEOPLE ARE
GOING TO MOVE BEYOND THAT.
AND ALSO THIS WHOLE NOTION OF
THESE COUPLE OF DAYS BEING SO
IMPORTANT.
YOU KNOW, NOT PUTTING IT OFF,
MAKING SURE THAT IF IT'S GOING
TO BE DISCUSSED IT'S DISCUSSED
BECAUSE A LONGER -- THE LONGER
SYMPTOMS SORT OF LAST IN
CHILDREN AND ADULTS, THE HARDER
IT IS TO TREAT.
>> Reporter: MINNEAPOLIS NEW
HAVEN HOSPITAL HAS VOLUNTEERED A
COUNSELING LINE.
I WAS SURPRISED AND WONDERED IS
IT EFFECTIVE TO DO COUNSELING ON
PHONE, AS EFFECTIVE AS SEEING
SOMEONE IN PERSON?
>> I THINK IT VERY MUCH CAN BE.
THIS IS A NATIONALLY KNOWN
CENTER.
I'VE DEALT WITH THEM IN THE
PAST.
THEY HAPPEN TO BE CLOSE BY.
THEY DEAL WITH THESE TYPES OF
ISSUES ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
THEY SERVE AS A REMINDER THAT
THERE ARE MANY PEOPLE GOING
THROUGH THIS.
WHEN YOU'RE GOING THROUGH THIS,
YOU TEND TO THINK THAT IT'S YOU,
YOUR OWN INDIVIDUAL EXPERIENCE
THAT HAS LED YOU TO FEELING THIS
WAY.
EVERYONE IN THE HUNT, AS YOU
MENTIONED, YOU AND ME, BOTH
PARENTS, SO MANY PEOPLE ARE
GOING THROUGH THIS.
>> Reporter: SANJAY, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
I APPRECIATE YOUR INSIGHT ON
THAT.
WE KNOW LOTS ABOUT THE SCENE SO
FAR.
BUT VERY LITTLE ABOUT THE
VICTIMS.
VERY LITTLE ABOUT THE SHOOTER.
NOT SO MUCH ABOUT THE CRIME
SCENE.
WE'RE GOING TO GET MORE DETAILS
ABOUT HOW THIS TERRIBLE TRAGEDY
UNFOLDED, THAT'S STRAIGHT AHEAD
AFTER THIS BREAK.
STAY WITH US.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS SHELDON, WHOSE LONG DY
SETTING UP THE NEWS
STARTS WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND A CHOICE.
TAKE TYLENOL OR TAKE ALEVE,
THE #1 RECOMMENDED PAIN
RELIEVER BY ORTHOPEDIC DOCTORS.
JUST TWO ALEVE
CAN KEEP PAIN AWAY ALL DAY.
BACK TO THE NEWS.
YOU WANNA SEE IF WALMART HAS
SIMILAR GIFTS FOR LESS?
YEAH.
LET'S GO.
SAMSUNG GALAXY S3 --
OVER FIFTY DOLLARS LESS
THAN BEST BUY!
WOW! FIFTY BUCKS!
YEAH!
THAT'S A PAIR OF SHOES.
SEE FOR YOURSELF IF YOU COULD
SAVE ON THE GIFTS YOU WANT.
WALMART.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
>>> THE VICTIMS HAVE BEEN
POSITIVELY IDENTIFIED BY THE
OFFICE OF THE CHIEF STATE'S
MEDICAL EXAMINER.
THEY'RE STILL IN THE PROCESS OF
DOING SOME WORK.
AS SOON AS THAT'S COMPLETED WE
WILL BE PREPARED TO RELEASE IN
WRITING TO YOU A FORMAL LIST OF
NAMES, BIRTHDAYS, AND
INFORMATION.
THERE'S A COUPLE OF FACTORS.
NUMBER ONE, WHEN WE RELEASE THE
LIST -- AND WE ASK YOU AGAIN AS
WE DID YESTERDAY AT THE REQUEST
OF ALL OF THE FAMILY MEMBERS,
THEY ASKED FOR YOU TO PLEASE
RESPECT THEIR PRIVACY.
THEY'RE GOING THROUGH AS I KNOW
YOU UNDERSTAND A VERY DIFFICULT
AND TRYING TIME WE HAVE
ASSIGNED, ASSIGNED A TROOPER TO
FOLKS TO HELP TO MAINTAIN THAT
SOLITUDE.
AGAIN, I WOULD ASK YOU, AND I'M
PLEADING WITH YOU, AS YOU KNOW
THIS IS EXTREMELY HEARTBREAKING,
DIFFICULT THING FOR THESE FOLKS
TO ENDURE.
>> Reporter: THAT WAS LIEUTENANT
VANCE WRAPPING UP THE PRESS
CONFERENCE.
MAKING IT VERY CLEAR THAT THE
PARENTS AND THE FAMILY MEMBERS
WHO LOST LOVED ONES ABSOLUTELY
ARE NOT TO BE BOTHERED AND TO
HAVE THEIR PRIVACY VIOLATED.
AND THESE GOING TO ASSIGN A
TROOPER TO EACH TO MAKE SURE
THAT THAT DOES NOT HAPPEN.
ONE OF THE THINGS THAT HE
REITERATEDED A COUPLE OF TIMES
WAS TO GET TO THE HOW AND WHY
THIS HAPPENED.
HE DESCRIBED IT AS PEELING BACK
THE PIECES OF THE ONION, TO
REALLY UNDERSTAND NOT ONLY THE
TIMELINE OF LITERALLY HOW THIS
TRAGEDY UNFOLDED BUT THE WHY.
PEOPLE WOULD LIKE TO UNDERSTAND
THE WHY AND MAYBE IT'S NOT
SOMETHING THAT CAN BE
UNDERSTOOD.
WE'RE GETTING MORE INFORMATION,
AS WELL, FROM SOME OF THE FOLKS
WHO LIVED THROUGH THIS TERRIBLE
TRAGEDY, DESCRIBING WHAT
HAPPENED AROUND THEM AS THEY
COULD HEAR THE SHOOTING AND THE
SCREAMING IN THE HALLWAYS.
THERE'S A LIBRARY CLERK WE SPOKE
TO WHO SAID THEY HAD BEEN
PRACTICING FOR THESE KINDS OF
DRILLS WE HAVE HER STORY.
>>> WE'VE BEEN HEARING FOR 24
HOURS THE STORIES OF HAROR.
THE HEARTBREAK FROM -- HORROR.
THE HEARTBREAK FROM THE
CHILDREN, FAMILIES, LAW
ENFORCEMENT.
WE'RE ALSO HEARING ABOUT HEROES.
ONE IS THE SCHOOL LIBRARY CLERK,
MARY ANN JACOB.
WE SPOKE WITH HER MOMENTS AGO.
SHE TALKED ABOUT WHAT SHE DID TO
KEEP KIDS SAFE DURING THE
SHOOTING.
LISTEN.
>> EVERYBODY DOES WHAT THEY HAVE
TO DO WHEN THEY'RE CONFRONTED
WITH A SITUATION LIKE THAT.
AND EVERYBODY, YOU KNOW, WE
PRACTICED IT.
AND THEY KNEW WHAT TO DO.
AND YOU JUST -- YOU THINK ABOUT
PROTECTING THE KIDS AND JUST
DOING THE RIGHT THING.
>> HOW HAD YOU PRACTICED THIS.
>> WE HAVE LOCKDOWN DRILLS.
I DON'T KNOW HOW MANY, BUT
THERE'S RULES.
YOU HAVE TO HAVE A CERTAIN
NUMBER OF FIRE DRILLS,
EVACUATION DRILLS, AND LOCKDOWN
DRILLS.
THE KIDS KNOW THE ROUTINE AND
TEACHERS KNOW THE ROUTINE.
EVERYONE HAS A SPOT THEY'RE
SUPPOSED TO GO TO.
>> CAN YOU DESCRIBE THE SPOT?
>> IN THE LIBRARY IT'S BETWEEN
SOME BOOK CASES AGAINST A WALL
WHERE YOU CAN'T BE SEEN FROM ANY
WINDOWS.
WE HAD TO MOVE OUT OF THAT SPOT
BECAUSE ONE OF OUR DOORS WASN'T
LOCKED WE DISCOVERED SO WE WENT
TO A BACK STORAGE ROOM AND
LOCKED THE KIDS IN THERE.
>> HOW DID YOU GET --
>> WE WERE THIS CLOSE TOGETHER.
>> HOW DID YOU GET THE CHILDREN
TO BE QUIET?
>> THERE WAS CRAYONS AND PAPER
IN THE STORAGE ROOM IN THE BACK.
WE TORE SOME UP AND GAVE THEM
CLIPBOARDS AND HAD THEIR COLOR
AND DRAW.
>> WHAT DID YOU TELL THEM --
>> WERE ALONE?
>> THERE WERE THREE OTHER
ADULTS.
THEY WERE ASKING WHAT WAS GOING
ON, WE SAID WE DON'T KNOW, OUR
JOB IS TO STAY QUIET.
IT MAY BE A DRILL, IT MAY NOT.
>> YOU DIDN'T KNOW AT THAT
POINT?
>> WE KNEW BECAUSE I CALLED THE
OFFICE, AND SHE TOLD ME THERE
WAS A SHOOTER.
MY KIDS, FRIEND OF THEIRS, HAVE
LITTLE BROTHERS OR SISTERS THAT
ARE DEAD.
EVERYBODY IN TOWN KNOWS
EVERYBODY.
I'M JUST GLAD THEY WERE SAFE.
WE WERE IN LOCKDOWN AND THEY
DIDN'T KNOW.
THE KIDS AT THE HIGH SCHOOL WERE
IN LOCKDOWN WATCHING.
THEY HAVE FAMILY.
THIS WAS PROBABLY DIFFICULT.
>> CAN YOU EXPLAIN IT --
>> CAN YOU EXPLAIN IT TO ME?
>> DID YOU KNOW THE MOTHER?
>> NO.
SHE WASN'T IN PLAY.
>> WHAT ABOUT THE PRINCIPAL?
EVERYONE'S SAYING WHAT A GREAT
PERSON SHE WAS, HOW MUCH DO YOU
--
>> SHE WAS A PERSONAL FRIEND AND
A WONDERFUL LEADER.
>> LAST NIGHT A TEACHER TOLD OUR
ANDERSON COOPER THAT SHE TOOK
THE KIDS IN HER CLASS INTO
ANOTHER ROOM AND JUST HAD THEM
READ, READ TOGETHER.
AND JUST TO HAVE THE WHEREWITHAL
TO BE ABLE TO DO THAT, TO HAVE
THE COMPOSURE TO WHILE THIS IS
HAPPENING KEEP THE CHILDREN CALM
AND MORE THAN ONE PARENT SAID,
SOLEDAD, THAT THE TEACHERS SAVED
THEIR CHILDREN'S LIVES.
THE ONES WHO WERE ABLE TO TAKE
THEIR CHILDREN HOME.
WE'RE GOING TO HEAR MORE ABOUT
THE HEROISM AS WE LEARN ABOUT
THE TRAGEDY AS THE DAYS GO ON.
SOLEDAD?
>> MY GOODNESS, VICTOR.
THESE TEACHERS ARE TRUE HEROES.
WHEN YOU HEAR WHAT THEY DID TO
TRY TO -- NOT JUST KEEP THEM
SAFE BUT KEEP THEM QUIET.
THEY WERE WORRIED IF THE GUNMAN
HEARD THE CHILDREN TALKING OR
ANYBODY MADE NOISE OR CRYING
THAT HE COULD TARGET THEIR
CLASSROOM.
SO TO BE ABLE TO DO THAT, KEEP
THEM CALM, DISTRACT THEM BECAUSE
THEY'RE SMALL CHILDREN AND THEY
NEEDED TO BE ABLE TO ALMOST BE
FOCUSED ON SOMETHING ELSE, WHAT
THEY HAD DONE IS NOTHING SHORT
OF HEROIC.
IT'S AN AMAZING THING.
VICTOR BLACKWELL REPORTING,
THANK YOU.
APPRECIATE IT.
WE'VE GOT TO TAKE A BREAK.
AS WE COME BACK IN A MOMENT
WE'LL CONTINUE TO UPDATE YOU ON
THE LATEST THAT WE KNOW ABOUT
THIS SHOOTING HERE AT A
CONNECTICUT ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE'RE BACK IN A MOMENT.
STAY WITH US.
THERE'S A HEALTH COMPANY THAT
CAN HELP YOU STAY THAT WAY.
WHAT'S HEALTHIER THAN THAT?
CUSTOMER ERIN SWENSON
BOUGHT SO, I'M HAPPY. TODAY.
SALES GO UP... I'M HAPPY.
IT WENT OUT TODAY... I'M HAPPY.
WHAT IF SHE'S NOT HOME?
(TOGETHER)
SHE WON'T BE HAPPY.
USE UPS! SHE CAN GET
A TEXT ALERT, REROUTE...
EVEN RESCHEDULE HER PACKAGE.
IT'S UPS MY CHOICE.
ARE YOU HAPPY?
I'M HAPPY.
HAPPY.
(TOGETHER)
I LOVE LOGISTICS.
>>> WELCOME BACK.
YOU'RE WATCHING OUR SPECIAL
COVERAGE OF THE SCHOOL SHOOTING
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE LEARNED FROM A CONFERENCE
THAT THE SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA,
GAINED ENTRY IN FACT INTO THE
SCHOOL BY FORCING HIS WAY
INSIDE.
WE HAD HEARD REPORTS THAT THERE
HAD BEEN A NEW SECURITY SYSTEM
SET UP FOR WHEN THE NEW
PRINCIPAL CAME IN.
ONCE HE GOT INSIDE, HE WAS ABLE
TO KILL 26 PEOPLE, ALL THE
WEAPONS THAT HE USED WERE
PURCHASED LEGALLY AND PURCHASED
IN FACT BY HIS MOTHER.
WE WANT TO BRING IN THE FORMER
FBI ASSISTANT DIRECTOR TOM
FUENTES.
ALSO A CNN CRIB ONTRIBUTOR.
WE HEARD IN THE PRESS CONFERENCE
THAT THE CRIME SCENE IS STILL
BEING PROCESSED.
TELL ME ABOUT WHAT THEY WOULD BE
DOING NOW.
THE BODIES WE KNOW ARE MOVED TO
A MORGUE.
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
>> THE SCENE AT THE INSIDE OF
THE SCHOOL WOULD BE TO TRACE THE
STEPS OF THE SHOOTER, WHERE DID
HE GO EVERY STEP OF THE WAY FROM
THE TIME HE GAINED ENTRY, WHICH
ROOMS HE WAS IN, WHERE HE WAS
WHEN HE FIRED THE SHOTS, WHERE
THE VICTIMS WERE WHEN THEY GOT
SHOT, AND TRY TO DETERMINE EVERY
STEP HE TOOK WHILE IN THERE
LEADING UP TO HIM TAKING HIS OWN
LIFE.
THAT PART IS VERY DIFFICULT.
THEY'RE TRYING TO TRACE THE
DIRECTION OF BULLET AND WHERE
THEY MAY HAVE HIT WALLS AND PICK
UP THE BULLET CASINGS THAT WOULD
HAVE BEEN SPRAYED OUT OF THE GUN
AS HE WAS SHOOTING OR THE TWO
GUNS AS HE WAS SHOOTING.
THAT'S A VERY DIFFICULT PROCESS.
TAKES A LOT OF METICULOUS WORK
ON THE CRIME SCENE
INVESTIGATORS.
OF COURSE YOU HAVE THE CRIME
SCENE OUTSIDE THE BUILDING, ANY
MATERIAL HE MAY HAVE DROPPED.
MAYBE HE WAS WALKING AROUND
BEFOREHAND OR HIS VEHICLE.
THEN OF COURSE AT HIS RESIDENCE
WHERE YOU HAVE PRESUMABLY HIS
MOTHER KILLED BEFORE HE DEPARTS
AND GOES TO THE SCHOOL AND
SHOOTS EVERYBODY ELSE.
SO THESE CRIME SCENES TAKE A LOT
OF PHYSICAL WORK TO PROCESS.
>> Reporter: THEY SAID THAT THEY
WERE GOING TO TRY TO FIND THE
HOW AND THE WHY.
AND HOW OFTEN, IN FACT, I THINK
THEY FIGURE OUT THE HOW.
THEY'RE ABLE TO PIECE TOGETHER
CLEARLY, EVENTUALLY, WHAT
UNFOLDED.
BUT HOW OFTEN IN CASES LIKE THIS
DO WE JUST NEVER REALLY KNOW THE
WHY?
AND BEFORE I LET YOU ANSWER, I
WANT TO TELL WHOEVER'S TALKING
IN MY EAR WHILE YOU'RE TALKING,
IT'S HARD TO HEAR.
IF YOU IN THE CONTROL ROOM WOULD
FIX, THAT I'M GETTING ANOTHER
FEED.
SOMEONE ELSE IS TALKING IN MY
EAR.
TOM, GO AHEAD, HOW LIKELY THAT
WE'RE GOING TO GET THE WHY IN
THIS CASE?
THE PROBLEM IS EVEN IF EXPERTS
SAY THEY KNOW WHY, DO THEY
REALLY?
AS MR. GUPTA SAID, MAYBE IT'S
UNKNOWABLE.
EVEN IF THEY GET EMAILS, EVEN IF
THEY GET CONVERSATIONS THAT HE'S
HAD WITH OTHER FRIENDS OR FAMILY
MEMBERS, NEIGHBORS, SOMEBODY
SAYING THAT HE WAS GOING DO THIS
OR WHY HE WAS GOING TO DO IT,
YOU DON'T KNOW THAT IT WAS
TRUTHFUL.
FOUN HE MEA
YOU DON'T KNOW IF HE MEANT IT,
IF HE WAS DELUSIONAL.
THERE'S SO MANY ASPECTS THAT
WE'RE NOT EVER GOING TO KNOW.
THERE WILL BE A LOT OF
SPECULATION BY EXPERTS, BUT
THEY'RE NOT GOING TO REALLY KNOW
POSITIVELY WHAT WAS ON HIS MIND
WHEN HE WENT TO COMMIT THESE
ACTS.
AND YOU KNOW, THE CLOSEST PERSON
TO HIM TO MOST PEOPLE WOULD BE
THEIR OWN MOTHER, SHE'S NOT
GOING TO BE AVAILABLE TO TALK
TO.
WHETHER HE WAS CLOSE WITH HIS
BROTHER OR FATHER, WE DON'T
KNOW.
YOU KNOW, WE ALSO DON'T KNOW WAS
THIS A CLOSE KNIT FAMILY GROWING
UP OR WERE THEY DYSFUNCTIONAL
AND HE WAS OFF ON HIS OWN
MENTALLY OR PSYCHOLOGICALLY.
AND SO I DON'T PUT A LOT OF
FAITH INTO THE SPECULATION.
INVESTIGATORS WILL DO EVERYTHING
THEY CAN TO PROFILE HIM AND SEE
WHAT WAS ON HIS MIND BUT THEY'RE
NEVER GOING TO KNOW POSITIVELY.
>> Reporter: HOW WOULD YOU
ASSESS THE JOB THAT THE LAW
ENFORCEMENT HERE DID FROM
LISTENING TO THOSE 911 CALLS AND
ALSO I THINK IN THE CONTEXT OF
KNOWING THAT THIS IS A COMMUNITY
THAT HASN'T HAD A HOMICIDE IN A
DECADE?
I DON'T THINK IT'S A PLACE WHERE
THEY ARE USED TO SHOOGSZ,
FRANKFRAN -- TO
SHOOTINGS, FRANKLY.
>> FORTUNATELY I DON'T THINK
MANY COMMUNITIES ARE USED TO A
MASS MURDER AT THEIR SCHOOLS.
THE SITUATION THE FIRST
RESPONDERS FACED WAS EXTREMELY
DIFFICULT.
APPEARS THEY HANDLED IT
PROFESSIONALLY AND DID A GOOD
JOB.
THEY DIDN'T KNOW IF THEY HAD
MULTIPLE SHOOTERS.
THEY DIDN'T KNOW IF SOMEONE HAD
LEFT AND WAS IN THE WOODS OR HAD
RUN INTO A NEIGHBORING HOUSE AND
WAS HOLDING A FAMILY HOSTAGE.
THEY DIDN'T KNOW WHERE ALL THE
CHILDREN WERE.
WE HAD REPORTS THAT SOME
CHILDREN WERE RUNNING THROUGH
THE FIELD AND THROUGH PEOPLE'S
BACK YARDS IN THE IMMEDIATE
AFTERMATH.
SO FOR POLICE TO ARRIVE AND
QUICKLY ASSESS WHAT IT OCCURRED
AND WHAT TO DO ABOUT IT, IT
APPEARS THAT THEY DID A VERY
PROFESSIONAL JOB.
NOW IN THE AFTERMATH OF IT, YOU
HAVE THE POLICE TRYING TO
CONTROL THE INFORMATION.
AND THIS IS A VERY DIFFICULT
TASK.
AND I THINK AN UNDERRATED TASK
FOR POLICE EXECUTIVES.
IF THE POLICE GIVE OUT TOO MUCH
INFORMATION TOO SOON, IT COULD
BE INACCURATE, IT COULD OBSTRUCT
THEIR OWN INVESTIGATION.
FRANKLY, IF THEY GIVE TOO LITTLE
INFORMATION, ENTERPRISING
REPORTERS NOT FROM CNN OF
COURSE, BUT SOME ENTERPRISING
REPORTERS WILL FILL THE VACUUM
WITH INACCURATE DATA, AND THAT
WILL ALSO CLOUD THE
INVESTIGATION.
SO IT'S A VERY DIFFICULT THING
TO ACTUALLY CONDUCT THE
INVESTIGATION, AND IT'S ALSO A
DIFFICULT THING TO DESCRIBE AND
REPORT ON THE INVESTIGATION TO
THE PUBLIC.
>> IT WAS INTERESTING TO HEAR
LIEUTENANT VANCE TALK ABOUT
ASSIGNING TROOPERS TO EACH
FAMILY THAT BASICALLY WANTED TO
ENSURE THEIR PRIVACY BECAUSE, OF
COURSE, THERE IS -- I'M GOING TO
GUESS LIKE 100 LIVE CAMERAS ALL
WIRED HERE IN THE PARKING LOT
FROM THE SORT OF THE HALF MILE
FROM THE SCHOOL WHERE WE ARE.
HE'S GOING TO PROTECT THEM FROM
THE NATIONAL AND INTERNATIONAL
MEDIA.
IS THAT UNUSUAL?
IT SEEMED TO BE A SMART THING.
>> VERY SMART THING.
LIEUTENANT VANCE HAS DONE AN
EXCEPTIONAL JOB IN THE WAY THAT
HE'S CONDUCTED PRESS CONFERENCES
FROM THE BEGINNING UNTIL AND
INCLUDING THIS MORNING.
THE DIFFICULTY HERE AND THE
POLICE ARE WELL AWARE OF WHAT'S
GOING TO HAPPEN, AS SOON AS THE
NAMES OF THOSE VICTIMS ARE
ACTUALLY RELEASED AND BECOME
PUBLIC THOSE FAMILIES ARE GOING
TO BE INUNDATED NO MATTER HOW
MUCH HE AND OTHERS PLEAD FOR THE
PRIVACY AND SOLITUDE OF THE
VICTIMS' FAMILIES.
FRANKLY, IT'S NOT GOING TO
COMPLETELY HAPPEN.
THERE ARE GOING TO BE PEOPLE,
EVEN WELL WISHERS CONTACTING
THEM THAT ARE THINKING THEY'RE
BEING HELPFUL.
UNFORTUNATELY, THERE WILL BE
PEOPLE TRYING TO EXPLOIT THEM
AND TAKE ADVANTAGE OF THE
SITUATION AND OF THE POOR
VICTIMS.
THERE'S A NUMBER OF ISSUES.
THE POLICE KNOW WHAT'S GOING
HAPPEN IN TERMS OF THE PRIVACY
OF THOSE FAMILY AS SOON AS THE
NAMES GO OUT.
THEY KNOW THE FAMILIES ARE IN
FOR A LOT OF TROUBLE IN THE DAYS
AHEAD.
>> Reporter: YEAH.
I HOPE THOSE TROOPERS KNOW
THEY'LL BE WORKING HARD TO KEEP
THE PRIVACY FOR THE FAMILY
MEMBERS.
TOM, THANK YOU.
FORMERLY WITH THE FBI.
WE APPRECIATE YOUR TIME AND
INSIGHT THIS MORNING.
WE HEARD FROM THE PRESIDENT
EARLIER CALLING FOR MEANINGFUL
ACTION IN THE WAKE OF THIS
TRAGEDY.
THERE'S ALSO THIS FROM THE NEW
YORK MAYOR, MICHAEL BLOOMBERG,
"CALLING FOR "MEANINGFUL ACTION"
IS NOT NUFD.
WE NEED IMMEDIATE ACTION.
WE HAVE HEARD ALL THE RHETORIC
BEFORE, WHAT WE'VE NOT SEEN IS
LEADERSHIP, NOT FROM THE WHITE
HOUSE AND NOT FROM CONGRESS.
THAT MUST END TODAY."
JOINING US IS CNN CONTRIBUTOR
MARIA CAR DON'T AAMY HOLMES OF
THE BLAZE.COM.
THE YEAS ARE A, YOU'VE GOT KIDS
I IMAGINE -- MARIA, YOU'VE GOT
KIDS I IMAGINE.
AND AMY, YOU HAVE REPORTED -- I
HAVE TO IMAGINE YOU'RE
HORRIFIED.
>> I KNOW THERE WAS NOT A DRY
EYE YESTERDAY, ESPECIALLY FROM
PARENTS.
I SAW YOU THIS MORNING CHOKING
UP.
AND EVERY SECOND I FEEL LIKE I'M
ABOUT TO CHOKE UP.
YES, THIS IS A NATIONAL TRAGEDY.
I AGREE FRANKLY WITH MAYOR
BLOOMBERG.
OUR LEADERS NEED TO STEP UP
INCLUDING PRESIDENT OBAMA.
I HOPE THAT HIS CALL FOR
MEANINGFUL ACTION WILL MEAN
IMMEDIATE ACTION.
THERE ARE TWO THINGS THAT WE CAN
DO IMMEDIATELY, THAT IS RENEW
THE BAN ON ASSAULT WEAPONS.
THERE'S NO REASON WHY THE
SHOOTER HAD THAT SEMIAUTOMATIC
RIFLE IN HIS POSSESSION.
THERE ALSO SHOULD BE A WAY TO
GET RID OF THE LOOPHOLE, THE GUN
SHOW LOOPHOLE WHERE 40% OF GUNS
ARE SOLD WITHOUT BACKGROUND
CHECKS.
THERE IS NO SANE, RATIONAL
REASON IN THE WORLD WHY THAT
SHOULD BE HAPPENING IN THIS
COUNTRY TODAY.
>> RIGHT.
BUT THE REALITY IS THAT ASSAULT
RIFLES, SEMIAUTOMATIC ASSAULT
RIFLE, THE BUSHMASTER 223, THAT
WAS IN THE CAR.
HE PULLED OFF THIS ATTACK USING
GUNS BUT NOT ASSAULT WEAPONS
BANNED IN THIS PARTICULAR CASE.
PROBABLY WOULDN'T HAVE HAD AN
IMPACT.
AMY HOLMES, I KNOW IT'S NOT JUST
REPUBLICANS.
THERE ARE PLENTY OF DEMOCRATS,
TOO, WHO GET ANTSY WHEN PEOPLE
START TALKING ABOUT GUN CONTROL.
AND PUTTING LIMITS ON THE
ABILITY TO OWN GUNS.
SO WHAT DOES MEANFUL ACTION IN
YOUR MIND MEAN?
>> WELL, I THINK AS LIEUTENANT
VANCE SAID, WE NEED TO PEEL BACK
THE ONION AND UNDERSTAND HOW HE
DID GET POTISSESSION OF THE GUN.
AS WE UNDERSTAND, THEY WERE
REGISTERED TO HER MOTHER.
WHY THEY WERE AVAILABLE IS HARD
TO KNOW.
I THINK ONE THING WE CAN DO IN
TERMS OF MEANINGFUL ACTION IS
NOT TO GLORIFY THESE VILLAINS
AND THESE KILLERS AND NOT TO USE
THEIR NAMES, NOT TO REFERENCE
THEM DIRECTLY.
ONE OF THE THINGS THAT WE'VE
BEEN LEARNING WITH THESE MASS
SHOOTERS THEY THEY DO SORT OF
REVEL IN THEIR NOTE RIGHT AND
THEY DO SEEK NOTORIETY.
SO I WOULD ASK ALL OF US NEVER
TO USE THE NAME OF THE SHOOTER
EVER.
>> WE'VE BEEN TRYING TO DO THAT.
AT THE SAME TIME --
>> IT'S A DIFFICULT THING, AND
OF COURSE WE HAVE A CONSTITUTION
AND A FIRST AMENDMENT.
BUT WE ALSO HAVE JUDGMENT AND
DISCERNMENT.
WE KNOW, FOR EXAMPLE, THAT WE
DON'T SHOW THE BODIES OF
VICTIMS.
I THINK THAT WE CAN TREATED THIS
WITH A BIT MORE SENSITIVITY TO
SOME OF THE DYNAMICS THAT GO IN
TO CREATING THESE MASS SHOOTERS
WHO APPARENTLY WANT ALL OF THE
NATION AND ALL OF THE WORLD'S
ATTENTION ON THEM.
>> I'M GOING TO STOP YOU THERE.
I'M HAVING A HARD TIME HEARING.
I HAVE SOMEBODY ELSE'S VOICE IN
MY EAR.
BEFORE I CARRY ON A CONVERSATION
ABOUT GUN CONTROL, I NEED TO
HEAR WHAT YOU'RE SAYING.
MARIA, I'M GOING TO ASK YOU A
FIRST QUESTION AND ASK AMY TO
RESPOND.
GUYS IN THE CONTROL ROOM, YOU'VE
GOT TO GET THIS VOICE THAT'S
BEING REPORTED OUT OF MY EAR.
MARIA, FOR YOU, YOU LAID OUT
SOMETHING TO DO -- I DON'T KNOW
THAT I WOULD AGREE WITH YOU THAT
THAT'S MEANINGFUL ACTION.
WHAT YOU HAVE DESCRIBED, THE
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN, IT WOULDN'T
DO ANYTHING IN THIS PARTICULAR
CASE.
AMY, WHAT YOU LAID OUT ALSO
WOULDN'T DO ANYTHING
SPECIFICALLY AND REALISTICALLY,
RIGHT?
I MEAN NOT SAYING THE SHOOTER'S
NAME, I AGREE 100%.
BUT IT'S NOT GOING TO CHANGE
ANYTHING ABOUT THE NEXT SHOOTING
THAT IS GOING TO HAPPEN AT SOME
POINT.
GO BACK TO THE DRAWING BOARD AND
TELL ME WHAT MEANINGFUL ACTION
THAT COULD STOP SHOOTINGS WOULD
BE AND MAYBE THE ANSWER IS THERE
IS NONE.
THEN I'D LIKE TO HEAR THAT.
MARIA?
>> SURE.
MAYBE, AND YOU COULD BE RIGHT.
I THINK WHERE WE CAN STAND TO --
WHERE WE CAN START IS ACTUALLY
THINGS THAT MAKE SENSE.
AND YOU'RE RIGHT, IN THIS
PARTICULAR INSTANCE, SOLEDAD,
PERHAPS THE BAN ON THE ASSAULT
WEAPON WOULD NOT HAVE MADE ANY
DIFFERENCE.
BUT WHAT ABOUT THE NEXT TIME?
AND WHAT IF HE HAD HAD THIS WITH
HIM, THE CARNAGE WOULD HAVE BEEN
MUCH WORSE THAN IT WAS.
AND SO WE HAVE TO BE LOOKING AT
WHAT CAN WE DO TO MAKE SURE THIS
DOESN'T HAPPEN AGAIN.
WE CAN'T DO ANYTHING ABOUT WHAT
JUST HAPPENED.
WE HAVE TO CONTINUE TO LOOK AT
NEXT TIME.
AGAIN, I SAY THE --
>> I'M GOING INTERRUPT YOU.
I'M HAVING A HARD TIME HEARING
YOU.
WHILE WE FIX OUR AUDIO, I'LL
STOP YOU THERE.
I KNOW THIS CONVERSATION ABOUT
GUN CONTROL IS GOING TO BE ONE
THAT WE ARE JUST STARTING TODAY
AND IS GOING TO CONTINUE ON.
MARIA, AMY, I'M SORRY FOR THE
AUDIO PROBLEMS, LADIES.
MY APOLOGIES.
>> THANKS.
I YOU'LL WANT TO STAY WITH CNN
AS WE CONTINUE OUR COVERAGE OF
THE TRAGEDY AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THAT COVERAGE WILL CONTINUE
RIGHT AFTER THIS SHORT BREAK.
AMERICANS ARE ALWAYS READY TO
WORK HARD FOR A BETTER FUTURE.
SINCE AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL
WAS FOUNDED BACK IN 1894,
THEY'VE BEEN COMMITTED
TO PUTTING CLIENTS FIRST.
HELPING GENERATIONS
THROUGH TOUGH TIMES.
GOOD TIMES.
NEVER TAKING A BAILOUT.
THERE WHEN YOU NEED THEM.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
OVER THE CENTURIES.
THE STRENGTH OF
A GLOBAL FINANCIAL LEADER.
THE HEART OF
A ONE-TO-ONE RELATIONSHIP.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
>>> GOOD MORNING, I'M WOLF
BLITZER COMING TO YOU LIVE IF
THE NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, THE
SCENE  A HORRIFIC, HORRIFIC
TRAGEDY.
WE'RE HERE IN NEW ENGLAND, THE
TOWN THAT BECAME THE SCENE OF
THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL MASSACRE.
WE'RE WATCHING ALL OF THE
DEVELOPMENTS, THERE ARE MANY
DEVELOPMENTS COMING IN.
WE'LL LEARN, FOR EXAMPLE, THE
NAMES AND VICTIMS OF THIS
ATTACK, 20 CHILDREN BETWEEN 5
AND 10 DIED IN THE SHOOTING
SPREE ALONG WITH SIX ADULTS.
AMONG THEM, THE SCHOOL'S BELOVED
CHILDREN AND THE SCHOOL'S
PSYCHOLOGIST, AS WELL.
DEVELOPMENTS COMING IN
DRAMATICALLY NOW.
WE'RE LIVE HERE IN NEWTOWN.
NICK VALENCIA IS JOINING US FROM
THE SNER CENTCNN CENTER WITH MO
BACKGROUND.
WE'RE AWAITING WORD ON THE
OFFICIAL ANNOUNCEMENT OF THE
VICTIMS.
IT'S GOING TO BE A VERY SAD
MOMENT FOR OUR VIEWERS.
CERTAINLY FOR PEOPLE ALL OVER
THE WORLD.
SET THE SCENE.
GIVE US THELIFT.
>> Reporter: IT'S BEEN A SOMBER
DAY IN THE CNN NEWSROOM AS WELL
AS ACROSS THE UNITED STATES, NO
DOUBT.
EARLIER THIS MORNING I SPOKE
WI
WITH EONE OF THE TEACHERS WHO WS
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
BEING CALLED A HERO.
SHE WAS THERE AT THE SCHOOL WHEN
THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER STORMED
INSIDE THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
WOLF.
WHAT HAPPENED WAS SHE WAS
BARRICADED INSIDE OF A
CLASSROOM, PROTECTING A GROUP OF
CHILDREN, PROTECTING HER
CHILDREN, FROM THIS ATTACKER.
HE WAS POUNDING ON THE DOOR, SHE
SAID.
I SPOKE TO HER VERY BRIEFLY THIS
MORNING.
IT WAS A VERY EMOTIONAL
CONVERSATION, AS YOU CAN
IMAGINE.
SHE SAID IT WAS VERY DIFFICULT
TO TALK TO ME THIS MORNING.
BUT SHE SAID THAT HER HEART AND
PRAYERS WAS WITH HER FRIENDS AND
THE FAMILY MEMBERS OF THOSE THAT
LOST LOVED ONES.
WOLF?
>> STAND BY.
LET ME UPDATE OUR VIEWERS ON THE
LATEST ON THE INVESTIGATION.
WE'RE LEARNING MORE DISTURBING
DETAILS ABOUT THE SHOOTING AND
THE 26 VICTIMS.
ONCE AGAIN, 20 VICTIMS CHILDREN.
POLICE JUST WRAPPED UP A NEWS
CONFERENCE HERE IN NEWTOWN.
THEY SAY ALL THE VICTIMS NOW
HAVE BEEN IDENTIFIED, THEIR
BODIES HAVE BEEN REMOVED FROM
THIS LITTLE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
GRADES KING COUNTY ER GADERGART
FOURTH GRADE, TAKEN TO THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER'S OFFICE.
THEY PLAN TO RELEASE THE NAMES
SHORTLY.
CRIME SCENE INVESTIGATORS ARE
WORKING AROUND THE CLOCK.
>> WE STILL HAVE MAJOR CRIME
DETECTIVES AND NEWTOWN
DETECTIVES WORKING AT THE SCENE
IN THE SCHOOL.
THAT IS NOT COMPLETED.
THAT PROBABLY WILL NOT BE
COMPLETED FOR AT LEAST ANOTHER
DAY AND A HALF TO TWO DAYS.
I'M PUTTING A TIME LIMIT ON IT,
IT COULD TAKE LONGER.
AS I EXPLAINED AT PREVIOUS PRESS
CONFERENCES, WE'VE DONE
EVERYTHING WE NEED TO DO TO
LITERALLY PEEL BACK THE ONION
LAYER BY LAYER AND EXAMINE EVERY
CRACK AND CREVICE OF THAT
FACILITY.
AND THAT DOES NOT INCLUDE OR
EXCLUDE I SHOULD SAY THE OUTSIDE
OF THE BUILDING.
THE OUTSIDE OF THE BUILDING'S
ALSO PART OF THE CRIME SCENE,
EVERY SINGLE VEHICLE IN THAT
LOT.
SO IT'S GOING TO BE A LONG,
PAINSTAKING PROCESS.
THE SECONDARY CRIME SCENE WAS
DISCOVERED PURSUANT TO THE
INVESTIGATION.
ONCE WE HAD A TENTATIVE
IDENTIFICATION OF THE SUSPECT,
WE BEGAN DOING A GREAT DEAL OF
WORK.
AGAIN, PEELING BACK THE ONION,
EVERYTHING WE COULD FIND OUT
ABOUT THE SUSPECT INCLUDING AND
NOT LIMITED TO RELATIVES,
FRIENDS, CO-WORKERS, FORMER
STUDENTS, LOCATION OF RESIDENTS.
AND ALL THOSE AREAS HAD TO BE --
PEOPLE HAD TO BE INTERVIEWED AND
AREAS HAD TO BE EXAMINED.
HENCE THAT CAUSED US TO
DISCOVERY THE SECONDARY CRIME
SCENE, A PRIVATE RESIDENCE WITH
A SOLE FEMALE DECEASED.
>> THAT WOMAN IS IDENTIFIED AS
NANCY LANZA.
SHE'S THE MOTHER OF THE SHOOTER
IDENTIFIED AS 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM
LAN
LANZA.
POLICE HAVE GATHERED WHAT THEY
CALL GOOD EVIDENCE ON THE
POSSIBLE MOTIVE FOR THIS DEADLY
PAM RAGE.
THEY'RE NOT RELEASE -- RAMPAGE.
THEY'RE NOT RELEASING THAT
YESTERDAY.
WE EXPECT THAT AHEAD.
SCHOOL EMPLOYEES WHO WERE INSIDE
THE SCHOOL DURING THE SHOOTING
ARE STARTING TO COME FORWARD TO
DESCRIBE THEIR HARROWING ORDEAL.
EARLIER THIS MORNING, THE
SCHOOL'S LIBRARIAN DESCRIBED
WHAT SHE DID WHEN SHE REALIZED
SOMETHING TERRIBLY WRONG WAS
GOING ON.
>> EVERYBODY DOES WHAT THEY HAVE
TO DO WHEN THEY'RE CONFRONTED
WITH A SITUATION LIKE THAT.
AND EVERYBODY, YOU KNOW, WE
PRACTICED IT, AND THEY KNEW WHAT
TO DO.
AND YOU JUST -- YOU THINK ABOUT
PROTECTING THE KIDS AND DOING
THE RIGHT THING.
>> HOW HAD YOU PRACTICED THIS?
>> WE HAVE LOCKDOWN DRILLS.
I DON'T REMEMBER HOW MANY, BUT
THERE'S RULES.
YOU HAVE TO HAVE A CERTAIN
NUMBER OF FIRE DRILLS,
EVACUATION DRILLS, LOCKDOWN
DRILLS.
EVERYONE HAS A ROUTINE, EVERYONE
HAS A SPOT IN THE ROOM THEY'RE
SUPPOSED TO GO TO.
>> CAN YOU DESCRIBE THE SPOT?
>> IN THE LIBRARY IT'S BETWEEN
BOOK CASES AGAINST A WALL WHERE
YOU CAN'T BE SEEN FROM ANY
WINDOW.
WE HAD TO MOVE OUT OF THE SPOT
BECAUSE ONE OF OUR DOORS WASN'T
LOCKED WE DISCOVERED.
WE WENT TO A BACK STORAGE ROOM.
>> HOW CLOSE --
>> WE WERE LIKE THIS CLOSE
TOGETHER.
>> HOW DID YOU KEEP THE CHILDREN
QUIET?
>> THERE WAS CRAYONS AND PAPER
IN THE BACK.
WE TORE SOME UP AND GAVE THEM
CLIPBOARDS.
>> WHAT DID YOU TELL THEM?
>> WERE YOU ALONE?
>> THERE WERE THREE OTHER
ADULTS.
THEY WERE ASKING WHAT WAS GOING
ON, WE SAID WE DON'T KNOW, OUR
JOB IS TO STAY QUIET.
IT MAY BE A DRILL, IT MAY NOT.
>> WHAT DID YOU KNOW AT THAT
POINT?
>> WE KNEW.
I CALLED THE OFFICE, AND SHE
TOLD ME THERE WAS A SHOOTER.
>> ONCE AGAIN, THERE ARE
IMPORTANT DEVELOPMENTS UNFOLDING
RIGHT NOW.
WE'RE HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE AWAITING WORD, OFFICIALS
WORD OF THE VICTIMS, THE NAMES
OF THE VICTIMS.
WE WANT TO WELCOME OUR VIEWERS
NOT ONLY HERE IN THE UNITED
STATES BUT AROUND THE WORLD WHO
ARE WATCHING.
THIS STORY CERTAINLY HAS
RESONATED AROUND THE WORLD.
CERTAINLY LEFT WITH A LOT OF
QUESTIONS THAT STILL NEED
ANSWERS THIS MORNING.
WE LEARNING POSSIBLE, THE
POSSIBLE MOTIVE OF THE SHOOTER,
THE 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA.
POLICE SAY THEY HAVE A GOOD
SENSE OF WHAT WAS GOING ON.
THEY HAVEN'T RELEASED THE
INFORMATION YET.
SAY HE KILLED HIS MOTHER BEFORE
THE RAMPAGE AT THE SCHOOL WHERE
HE THEN TOOK HIS OWN LIFE.
CNN'S MARY SNOW JOINING US FROM
OUTSIDE THE LANZA HOME IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WHAT HAVE WE LEARN GOOD ADAM
LANZA, THIS 20-YEAR-OLD MAN?
ARE WE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE
MOTIVE?
THE POLICE SEEM TO THINK THEY
HAVE A PRETTY GOOD IDEA OF WHAT
WAS GOING ON.
>> Reporter: YEAH, THEY ARE
PICKING UP INFORMATION, WOLF.
AND YOU KNOW, SHORTLY AFTER
YESTERDAY'S HORRIFIC SHOOTING,
POLICE WERE ON THE SCENE HERE AT
THE LANZA HOME WHERE IT'S
BELIEVED ADAM LANZA LIVED WITH
HIS MOTHER.
AND LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE
INDICATED THAT THEY ARE PICKING
UP INFORMATION PIECING TOGETHER,
POSSIBLY COULD LEAD TO THE
MOTIVE.
HE WAS ASKED AT THE PRESS
CONFERENCE JUST A SHORT TIME AGO
ABOUT WHETHER THERE WERE ANY
EMAILS OR MIGHTINWRITINGS THAT
GIVE INFORMATION.
>> OUR INVESTIGATORS AT THE
CRIME SCENE, THE SCHOOL AND
SECONDARILY AT THE SECONDARY
CRIME SCENE THAT WE DISCUSSED
WHERE THE FEMALE WAS LOCATED
DECEASED DID PRODUCE SOME VERY
-- VERY GOOD EVIDENCE IN THIS
INVESTIGATION THAT OUR
INVESTIGATORS WILL BE ABLE TO
USE IN HOPEFULLY PAINTEDING THE
COMPLETE PICTURE AS TO HOW AND
MORE IMPORTANTLY WHY THIS
OCCURRED.
>> Reporter: THE SECONDARY CRIME
SCENE THAT LIEUTENANT VANCE WAS
REFERRING TO IS THE HOME HERE.
YOU CAN'T SEE IT BEHIND ME, IT'S
BLOCKED BY POLICE.
BUT THE BODY OF THE SUSPECT'S
MOTHER WAS FOUND IN THE HOME
YESTERDAY.
AS FOR WHAT WE'RE LEARNING ABOUT
THE SUSPECT FROM NEIGHBORS HERE,
MANY ARE SAYING THIS WAS A KID
WHO WAS QUIET, WHO WAS DIFFERENT
IN SOME ESTIMATES, HE WAS CALLED
TROUBLED.
WE HEARD THE FAMILY WAS NOT THAT
SOCIAL.
THEY DIDN'T REALLY KNOW TOO MUCH
ABOUT THE FAMILY.
WOLF?
>> THERE WERE TWO PISTOLS AND A
RIFLE THAT WERE FOUND,
HIGH-CALIBER RIFLE, MARY.
WHAT ELSE DO WE KNOW ABOUT THE
WEAPONS?
>> Reporter: CNN HAS BEEN
REPORTING THOSE TWO PISTOLS WERE
FOUND, ACCORDING TO A LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIAL, WITH THE
BODY OF THE SHOOTER.
THE RIFLE WAS FOUND IN A CAR AT
THE SCHOOL.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI EARLIER
REPORTING THAT A LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIAL IS SAYING THAT HE MAY
HAVE HAD ACCESS TO AS MANY AS
FIVE WEAPONS.
WE'VE BEEN REPORTING THAT THREE
WEAPONS WERE RECOVERED.
AND CNN'S ALSO BEEN REPORTING
THAT THOSE GUNS WERE LOCALLY
PURCHASED BY THE -- WERE LEGALLY
PURCHASED BY THE SUSPECT'S
MOTHER.
>> WE DON'T KNOW HOW HE GOT
ACCESS OR ANYTHING ALONG THOSE
LINES.
I ASSUME THE POLICE ARE
INVESTIGATING ALL OF THAT.
IT WAS A BUSHMASTER
SEMIAUTOMATIC CALIBER RIFLE, AND
TWO PISTOLS, A GLOCK AND A SIG
SAUER, TWO PIOLS, AS WELL, ALL
FOUND AT THE SCENE.
AND THEY'RE INVESTIGATING
OBVIOUSLY THAT.
ANYTHING ELSE GOING ON OVER
THERE WHERE YOU ARE, MARY?
>> Reporter: THERE ISN'T, WOLF.
JUST THE POLICE ARE STILL HERE
ON THE SCENE.
IT IS A MUCH DIFFERENT SCENE
TODAY THAN YESTERDAY.
AS I MENTIONED, POLICE, SWAT
TEAMS WERE HERE YESTERDAY.
RESIDENTS HAD BEEN EVACUATED FOR
SEVERAL HOURS.
THEY HAVE BEEN ALLOWED BACK IN
THEIR HOME.
>> MARY SNOW WORKING THE STORY
FOR US, THE TRAGIC STORY INDEED.
MEANWHILE, INVESTIGATORS ARE
WORKING AROUND THE CLOCK TO TRY
TO ANSWER MANY OF THE QUESTIONS
THAT STILL ARE OUT THERE.
WE'RE ASKING THESE QUESTIONS,
INCLUDING THE KEY QUESTION WHY,
HOW COULD THIS HAPPEN.
RIGHT NOW THEY'RE TAKING A CLOSE
LOOK AT THE TRAGEDY, HOW IT
UNFOLDED, BEGINNING WITH FIRST
WORD THAT A SHOOTER WAS ON THE
SCENE.
>> SIX TO SEVEN SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL, CALLER IS INDICATING SHE
THINKS SOMEONE IS SHOOTING IN
THE BUILDING.
>> THE FRONT GLASS HAS BEEN
BROKEN -- THEY'RE NOT SURE WHY.
ALL UNITS, THE INDIVIDUAL THAT I
HAVE ON THE PHONE IS CONTINUING
TO HEAR WHAT HE BELIEVES TO BE
GUNFIRE.
UNITS RESPONDING TO SANDY HOOK
AT THIS TIME.
THE SHOOTING OCCURS TO THE -- TO
HAVE STOPPED.
THE SCHOOL IS IN LOCKDOWN.
>> CNN'S ANDERSON COOPER TAKES
US THROUGH WHAT WE KNOW AS OF
NOW, WHAT HAPPENED AT THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
[ SIRENS ]
>> ALL UNITS, THE INDIVIDUAL
THAT I HAVE ON THE PHONE IS
CONTINUING TO HEAR WHAT HE
BELIEVES TO BE GUNSHOTS.
>> Reporter: THE FIRST WORD WAS
CHILLING.
IT ONLY GOT WORSE.
>> THEY ARE REPORTING MULTIPLE
FATALITIES INVOLVED IN THE
SHOOTING AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
>> Reporter: WITH EACH NEW
REPORT, THE HORROR DEEPENED.
>> REPORTS SAY THE NUMBER OF
DEAD CLOSER TO 30 THAN 20.
AND SADLY, MOST OF THEM ARE
CHILDREN.
>> Reporter: EVERY DETAIL, EVERY
FACT BROUGHT MORE SADNESS.
EACH FRESH PIECE OF INFORMATION
A PART OF THE PICTURE.
A SCHOOL, KINDERGARTEN THROUGH
FOURTH GRAIT GRADDE.
A SANCTUARY THAT WAS SUPPOSED TO
BE A PLACE OF SAFETY TORN APART.
>> SHE HEARD, THE INTERCOM CAME
ON.
SHE HEARD A SCREAM AND TWO
GUNSHOTS.
AND THEN THE SCHOOL WENT INTO
LOCKDOWN.
>> Reporter: A STUDENT'S
TEENAGED BIG BROTHER DESCRIBING
THE SOUNDS OF THE GUNMAN ON THE
LOOSE AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
>> OFF-DUTY TROOPERS RESPONDED
TO THE SCHOOL.
WITH NEWTOWN POLICE IMMEDIATELY
UPON ARRIVAL ENTERED THE SCHOOL
AND BEGAN A COMPLETE ACTIVE
SHOOTER SEARCH OF THE BUILDING.
>> Reporter: THEY ARRIVED TO
CARNAGE.
THE KILLER, SAYS A LAW
ENFORCEMENT SOURCE WITH DETAILED
KNOWLEDGE, WAS DRESSED FOR
BATTLE IN BLACK FATIGUES AND
ARMED FOR MASS MURDER WITH TWO
PIFTD OLS A
PISTOLS AND MILITARY-STYLE
RIFLE.
IN THE SCHOOL STUDENTS WERE TOLD
TO HIDE IN CORNERS.
TEACHERS RISK EED THEIR LIVES T
PULL BOYS AND GIRLS TO SAFETY.
>> THANKFUL TO THE TEACHER WHO
SAVED THEM.
>> Reporter: YOU THINK THE
TEACHER SAVED HIS LIFE?
>> SHE DID.
HE HAD BULLET GOING BY AND SHE
GRABBED HIM AND ANOTHER CHILD
AND PULLED THEM INTO A
CLASSROOM.
>> Reporter: FRANTIC PARENTS
DESCENDED ON THE FIRE HOUSE.
>> TERRIFIED.
I'M STILL TERRIFIED, STILL IN
SHOCK.
I DON'T KNOW EVERYTHING THAT
HAPPENED.
I KNOW PEOPLE MISS WERE TAKEN TO
THE HOSPITAL.
>> Reporter: HIS SON'S OKAY, HIS
SON'S TEACHER WAS ALIVE, AS
WELL.
20 OTHER CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS
WERE KILLED.
THE DEAD BELIEVED TO INCLUDE
SANDY HOOK'S SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST
AND THE PRINCIPAL.
POLICE DISCOVERED ANOTHER ADULT
VICTIM, THE GUNMAN'S MOTHER.
REPORTEDLY AT HOME IN NEWTOWN.
THE GUNMAN, TOO, IS DEAD.
POLICE SAY THEY FIRED NO SHOTS.
A TIGHT-KNIT COMMUNITY INCLUDING
A NURSE WHO LIVED NEARBY AND
RUSHED TO HELP SHOCKED,
DISTRAUGHT.
I SEE YOU'VE BEEN CRYING.
>> YES.
>> Reporter: BECAUSE OF WHAT YOU
SAW?
>> ONE OF THE COPS SAID -- THE
WORST THING HE HAD SEEN IN HIS
CAREER.
BUT IT WAS WHEN THEY TOLD THE
PARENTS, ALL THESE PARENTS WERE
WAITING FOR THEIR CHILDREN TO
COME OUT.
THEY THOUGHT THAT THEY WERE, YOU
KNOW, STILL ALIVE.
THERE'S 20 PARENTS THAT WERE
JUST TOLD THEIR CHILDREN ARE
DEAD.
IT WAS AWFUL.
>> ANDERSON COOPER REPORTING.
PLEASE BE SURE TO TUNE IN, BY
THE WAY, TO "A.C. 360" SPECIAL
LATER ON THE TRAGIC SCHOOL
MASSACRE.
LIVE IN FREETOWN, CONNECTICUT,
ANDERSON WILL HAVE THE LATEST --
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, ANDERSON
WILL HAVE THE LATEST FROM THE
PEOPLE HERE.
TONIGHT A SPECIAL "A.C. 360,
"8:00 P.M. EASTERN.
FOR MORE INFORMATION ON HOW YOU
CAN HELP THOSE AFFECTED BY THE
SHOOTING, GO TO CNN.COM/IMPACT.
YOU WILL HAVE A CHANCE TO IMPACT
YOUR WORLD.
AS WE SAY, AS WE'VE BEEN
REPORTING, THREE WEAPONS WERE
FOUND AT THE SCHOOL.
TWO SEMIAUTOMATIC PISTOLS AND A
BUSHMASTER ASSAULT RIFLE.
ALL BELONG TO ADAM LANZA'S
MOTHER, NANCY LANZA.
CONTRIBUTOR AND FORMER FBI
DIRECTOR TOM FUENTES JOINS US
FROM WASHINGTON.
DEBORAH FEYERICK IS JOINING US.
TOM, FIRST YOU TO.
THESE ARE HIGH-POWERED GUNS
THE
THERE.
YOU OBVIOUSLY DOWNTOWN WAN'T WAN
THE WRONG HANDS.
CONNECTICUT HAS STRONG LAWS ON
THE BOOKS NOW.
HOW DID THE YOUNG ADAM LANZA,
20-YEAR-OLD, GET THESE WEAPONS?
>> HI, WOLF.
SO FAR WE DON'T KNOW FOR SURE
HOW HE GOT THEM.
THE REPORTS ARE THAT HIS MANAGER
LEGALLY PURCHASED THE WEAPONS
AND LEGALLY HAD THEM IN THE
HOUSE, IT FOLLOWED ALL OF THE
LAWS OF CONNECTICUT.
BUT IF HE WENT AHEAD AND STOLE
THEM FROM HIS MOTHER AND THEN
ACTUALLY USED THEM AGAINST HER
AND THE OTHER CHILDREN, THEN
THAT'S WHERE THE PROBLEM COMES
IN.
SHE MAY HAVE OBTAINED THE GUNS
LEGALLY, BUT HE DIDN'T.
HE BASICALLY WOULD HAVE STOLEN
THE WEAPONS.
>> HOW POPULAR OUT THERE ARE
THESE THREE KINDS OF WEAPONS?
THE TWO PISTOLS, ONE RIFLE?
HOW POPULAR OUT THERE ARE THEY
GENERALLY ACROSS THE COUNTRY?
>> THEY'RE POPULAR BECAUSE THE
GLOCK AND THE SIG SAUER PISTOLS
ARE PROFESSIONAL,
TOP-OF-THE-LINE QUALITY.
THEY'RE CARRIED BY MOST LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICERS, FEDERAL,
STATE, AND LOCAL THROUGHOUT THE
UNITED STATES BECAUSE THEY'RE
TOP-QUALITY REPRY.
T
THE BUSHMASTER IS A SPINOFF OR
NON- AUTOMATAUTOMATIC VERSION OS
FIRING THAT .223 BULLET WHICH IS
VERY, VERY LETHAL.
IT'S A MILITARY-GRADIVELY WITH E
WEAP
-- GRADE WEAPON.
THE FACT THAT IT'S NOT FULLY
AUTOMATIC DOESN'T MEAN IT'S NOT
VERY LEETHD THAL.
>> DEB, GO AHEAD.
>> ONE OF THE QUESTIONS, TOM,
YOU'VE WORKED A NUMBER OF CASES
LIKE THIS.
WHY NOT JUST KILL YOURSELF?
WHY GO AFTER PEOPLE WHO ARE THE
MOST VULNERABLE?
WHAT DOES THAT TELL YOU ABOUT
THE SHOOTER?
>> YOU KNOW, IT'S HARD TO SAY.
WHAT WAS IN HIS MIND OR ON HIS
MIND AT THE TIME HE CARRIED ALL
THESE ACTIONS OUT, WE'LL
PROBABLY NEVER KNOW FOR SURE.
I KNOW EXPERTS ARE GOING TO
THEORIZE THIS IS WHAT HE WAS
THINKING, THIS IS WHY HE DID IT,
OR HE WANTS HIS 15 MINUTES OF
FAME BY DOING A HORRENDOUS ACT
THAT WOULD OBTAIN WORLDWIDE
MEDIA ATTENTION AND FAME FOR
HIM.
BUT WE DON'T KNOW FOR SURE.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT TRIGGERED HIM
TO TAKE THIS OUT.
AND UNFORTUNATELY, HOOS NE'S NO
AVAILABLE TO ASK AND MIGHT NOT
HAVE BEEN HONEST IF HE DID
SURVIVE.
HIS MOTHER WOULD KNOW HIM BEST.
AND SHE'S NOT AVAILABLE TO ASK
WHAT WAS ON HER SON'S MIND.
WE DON'T KNOW, AND WE MAY NEVER
KNOW.
>> AND OUT OF CURIOSITY, DO YOU
KNOW IN THESE KINDS OF
SITUATIONS WITH SOMEBODY WHO IS
INTENT ON DOING SOMETHING, IS
THERE A MOMENT WHERE SOMEBODY
CAN INTERCEDE, WHERE SOMEBODY
CAN TRY TO TALK THEM DOWN FROM
WHAT IT IS THEY'RE DOING, OR
ONCE THEY'RE IN, ARE THEY
COMMITTED TO CARRYING OUT THIS
KIND OF HORROR?
>> THEY MAY BE COMMITTED.
AND THIS BRINGS UP A WHOLE OTHER
TOUCHY SUBJECT.
THAT IS, THE MENTAL HEALTH
SYSTEM IN THE UNITED STATES.
PARENTS REPORT REPEATEDLY HOW
HELPLESS THEY FEEL IN TERMS OF
BEING ABLE TO CALL THE POLICE
AND SAY, "I THINK MY SON'S OUT
OF CONTROL, I THINK HE'S GOING
TO DO A TERRIBLE THING."
UNFORTUNATELY, UNTIL THAT
TORNADO DOPERSON
DOES THE TERRIBLE THING, THERE'S
NOT MUCH WE CAN DO SO IT'S
PREVENTED.
SO WE HAVE A VERY INADEQUATE
MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEM, AND IT'S
GOING TO REQUIRE A LOT OF
RESOURCES AND CHANGES IN THE LAW
TO MAKE IT MORE EFFECTIVE AND TO
GIVE PARENTS AND FAMILY MEMBERS
AND LAW ENFORCEMENT AND DOCTORS
THE ABILITY TO INTERVENE AND TRY
TO DO SOMETHING BEFORE SOMEBODY
GOES OFF THE EDGE LIKE HE DID,
IF THEY KNOW THAT'S COMING.
IN SOME CASES THAT MAY NOT BE
CLEAR THAT IT'S PREVENTABLE.
PROBABLY A LARGE NUMBER WOULD BE
PREVENTABLE IN THE FUTURE IF WE
HAD THAT SYSTEM.
THE ISSUES THAT COME UP IN THESE
MASS SHOOTINGS ARE A COMBINATION
OF AN INADEQUATE MENTAL HEALTH
SYSTEM AND TREMENDOUS
AVAILABILITY OF HIGH-POWER
WEAPONS THROUGHOUT OUR SOCIETY.
>> WOLF, I'M SURE YOU'RE SEEING
IT THERE ON THE GROUND IN TERMS
OF PEOPLE ASKING WAS THERE A
MOTIVE.
IN THE END, WOLF, I'M SURE THE
ANSWER YOU'RE GETTING IS IT
DOESN'T MATTER THAT THERE'S A
MOTIVE.
YOU'VE GOT 26 PEOPLE, 27 PEOPLE
WHO ARE DEAD NOW, WOLF.
>> YEAH, A SAD STORY, INDEED.
TOM, WE DID LEARN TWO IMPORTANT
NUGGETS FROM THE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE, LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE, WHO JUST SPOKE TO
REPORTERS HERE.
FIRST THING HE POINTED OUT -- I
WANT YOUR REACTION.
HE SAID OUR INVESTIGATIONS DID
PRODUCE GOOD EVIDENCE IN THIS
INVESTIGATION THAT OUR
INVESTIGATORS WILL BE ABLE TO
USE TO PAINT A COMPLETE PICTURE.
SO WHAT -- WHEN YOU HEAR THAT
FROM THE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE, WHAT ARE YOU -- WHAT DO
YOU THINK?
WHAT KIND OF EVIDENCE DID THEY
PRODUCE AT THE CRIME SCENE?
DID THEY FIND AT THE CRIME SCENE
THAT HELPS ALL OF US BETTER
UNDERSTAND WHY THIS COULD
HAPPEN?
>> THERE'S A POSSIBILITY THAT
THE SHOOTER MAY HAVE BEEN
CARRYING SOME TYPE OF A NOTE OR
PERSONAL MANIFESTO WHERE HE'S
SAYING GOOD-BYE TO THE WORLD.
AND INDICATING THROUGH THAT WHY
HE WANTS TO DO THIS.
WE DON'T KNOW THAT FOR SURE.
BUT CERTAINLY THAT'S POSSIBLE
THAT HE MAY HAVE HAD SOMETHING
ON HIS PERSON OR AROUND HIS BODY
THAT -- THAT IS USEFUL FOR THE
INVESTIGATORS TO TRY TO FIND OUT
WHAT THE MOTIVE WAS OR HAVE AN
INDICATION OF MOTIVE.
THAT COULD BE -- ONE OF THE
THINGS HE COULD HAVE SAID TO
SOMEBODY THAT HASN'T BEEN MADE
PUBLIC YET.
THAT'S ANOTHER POSSIBILITY FROM
THE CRIME SCENE.
THOSE THINGS -- AGAIN, THE
PAPERWORK THAT WAS WITH HIM, THE
WALLET THAT HE WAS CARRYING, AND
ANY COMMENTS HE MAY HAVE MADE
PRIOR TO TAKING HIS OWN LIFE MAY
BE WHAT HE'S TALKING ABOUT.
>> AND THE OTHER NUGGET, THE
OTHER NEW PIECE OF INFORMATION
THAT THE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE SPOKESMAN SAID, IT WAS
THE SHOOTER -- AND I'M BEING
SPECIFIC, IT'S THE SHOOTER
FORCED HIS WAY INTO THE SCHOOL.
SO MAYBE THE DOORS WERE LOCKED.
HE FORCED HIS WAY, WHAT DOES
THAT SAY TO YOU?
>> WELL, THAT -- PEOPLE HAVE
TALKED ABOUT THIS GREAT SECURITY
SYSTEM THEY HAD.
AND ESSENTIALLY, IT'S A LOCKED
DOOR WITH A DOORBELL AND CAMERA
WHERE SOMEBODY IN THE FRONT
OFFICE CAN BUZZ PEOPLE IN IF
THEY RECOGNIZE THEM OR GO TO THE
DOOR AND HAVE THEM PRODUCE AN
I.D. AND SAY WHY THEY'RE AT THE
SCHOOL, WHAT PURPOSE THEY'VE
COME FOR.
SO IN THIS CASE, WE DON'T KNOW,
THERE WERE SOME REPORTS THAT HE
SHOT THE DOOR, SHOT THE GLASS,
AND ALLOWED HIMSELF IN.
SOMEONE MIGHT HAVE -- HE MAY
HAVE BUZZED AND SOMEONE CAME TO
THE DOOR, AND THEN HE PUSHED IT
OPEN WHEN THEY OPENED TO SEE
IDENTIFICATION.
AGAIN, THAT'S SOMETHING THEY'RE
STILL HOLDING CLOSELY IN TERMS
OF THE INVESTIGATION AS HOW
EXACTLY HE MADE THAT ENTRY.
>> THE PICTURE IS BEGINNING TO
BECOME LITTLE BIT MORE COMPLETE,
BUT THERE ARE STILL SO MANY
UNANSWERED QUESTIONS.
TOM FUENTES, YOU'LL STAY WITH
US.
DEBORAH FEYERICK'S GOING TO STAY
WITH US.
PRESIDENT OBAMA DEDICATED HIS
ENTIRE WEEKLY ADDRESS THIS
MORNING TO THE MASS SHOOTING
HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
HE CALLED ON THE NATION TO RALLY
AROUND THE FAMILIES OF THOSE
KILLED AND THE FAMILIES OF THE
SURVIVING STUDENTS, SAYING THEIR
INNOCENCE HAS BEEN TORN AWAY FAR
TOO EARLY.
>> THIS WEEKEND, MICHELLE AND I
ARE DOING WHAT I KNOW EVERY
PARENT IS DOING, HOLDING OUR
CHILDREN AS CLOSE AS WE CAN AND
REMINDING THEM HOW MUCH WE LOVE
THEM.
THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CAN'T DO THAT
TODAY.
AND THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT
NOW BECAUSE WHILE NOTHING CAN
TAKE THE PLACE OF A LOST CHILD
OR LOVED ONE, ALL OF US CAN
EXTEND A HAND TO THOSE IN NEED.
TO REMIND THEM THAT WE'RE THERE
FOR THEM, THAT WE'RE PRAYING FOR
THEM, AND THAT THE LOVE THEY.
FOR THOSE THEY LOST ENDURES NOT
JUST IN THEIR OWN MEMORIES BUT
ALSO IN THEIR COMMUNITIES AND IN
THEIR COUNTRY.
>> MANY OF US, ALL OF US, I
THINK PEOPLE IN THE UNITED
STATES, INDEED AROUND THE WORLD,
TRYING TO MAKE SENSE OUT OF THIS
TRAGEDY.
THE QUESTIONS CONTINUE.
HOW DO YOU TURN AROUND AND
EXPLAIN WHAT HAS HAPPENED TO
YOUR YOUNG CHILDREN?
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE EXPERT
ADVICE ON THAT, OUR SPECIAL
COVERAGE FROM HERE IN
CONNECTICUT CONTINUES RIGHT
AFTER THIS.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS DECEMBER, REMEMBER --
WHAT STARTS
WITH ADDING A FRIEND...
♪
...COULD END
WITH ADDING A CLOSE FRIEND.
♪
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON,
OFFERING SOME OF OUR BEST
VALUES OF THE YEAR.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
OFFERING SOME OF OUR BEST
VALUES OF THE YEAR.
I'VE BEEN A SUPERINTENDENT
FOR 30 SOME YEARS AT MANY
DIFFERENT PARK SERVICE UNITS
ACROSS THE UNITED STATES.
THE ONLY TIME I'VE EVER
HAD A BREAK IS WHEN
I WAS ON MATERNITY LEAVE.
I HAVE RETIRED FROM DOING
THIS ONE THING THAT I LOVED.
NOW, I'M GOING TO BE
ABLE TO HAVE THE TIME
TO EXPLORE SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
IT'S LIKE ANOTHER CHAPTER.
>>> CHANGED THE LIVES OF SOME
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL CHILDREN
FOREVER.
AS THE KIDS FROM SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL RUSHED INTO THE ARMS OF
FRANTIC PARENTS AFTER COWERING
IN CLOSETS, HIDING UNDER DESKS,
MANY RECALL THE CHAOS AND THE
FEAR THAT THEY WITNESSED JUST A
FEW MINUTES AGO.
OUR BRIAN TODD HAS DETAILS.
>> Reporter: THE ACCOUNT OF A
YOUNG BOY SAID TO BE DELIVERING
AN ATTENDANCE REPORT TO THE
OFFICE AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL WHEN THE SHOOTINGS TOOK
PLACE IS SURREAL.
>> I SAW SOME OF THE BULLETS
GOING PAST THE HALL THAT I WAS
RIGHT NEXT TO, AND THEN A
TEACHER PULLED ME INTO HER
CLASSROOM.
>> Reporter: HE SAID HE HEARD
SOMEONE KICKING A DOOR.
HIS MOTHER CLINGING TO HIM HAD
WORDS OF THANKS.
>> I'M SO GRATEFUL TO THE
TEACHER WHO SAVED HIM.
>> Reporter: THANK YOU, YOU
THINK THE TEACHER SAVED HIS
LIFE?
>> SHE DEFINITELY DID.
HE IT BULLETS GOING BY HIM.
SHE GRABBED HIM AND ANOTHER
CHILD AND PULLED THEM INTO A
CLASSROOM.
>> Reporter: BRENDAN MURRAY, A
FOURTH GRADER, DESCRIBED THE
CHAOS.
>> I WAS IN THE GYM AT THE TIME.
SO THE TEACHERS -- WE HEARD LOTS
OF BANGS.
AND WE THOUGHT THAT IT WAS THE
CUSTODIAN KNOCKING STUFF DOWN,
WE HEARD SCREAMING.
AND SO WE WENT TO THE WALL, AND
WE SAT DOWN.
THEN THE POLICE CAME IN, LIKE,
IS HE IN HERE, THEN HE RAN OUT.
THEN OUR TEACHER, SOMEBODY
YELLED, "GET TO A SAFE PLACE."
WE WENT TO A CLOSET IN THE GYM
AND SAT THERE FOR A LITTLE
WHILE.
THEN THE POLICE WERE KNOCKING ON
THE DOOR, AND THEY'RE LIKE,
"WE'RE EVACUATING PEOPLE.
WE'RE EVACUATING PEOPLE."
>> Reporter: CNN IS ONLY AIRING
SOUND OF CHILDREN WHOSE PARENTS
GAVE PERMISSION.
AS ONE WOMAN WALKED AWAY FROM
THE SCHOOL SHE WAS HEARD CRY,
"WHY, WHY?"
A POLICEMAN WAS HEARD SAYING, IT
WAS THE WORST THING HE'D SEEN IN
HIS CAREER.
A NURSE FROM NEARBY DANBURY
HOSPITAL DESCRIBED THE SCENE AS
PARENTS WAITED FOR WORD ABOUT
THEIR CHILDREN.
>> ALL THESE PARENTS WERE
WAITING FOR THEIR CHILDREN TO
COME OUT.
THEY THEY THOUGHT THAT THEY WERE
STILL ALIVE.
THERE WERE 20 PARENTS WHO WERE
JUST TOLD THEIR CHILDREN WERE
DEAD.
IT WAS AWFUL.
>> Reporter: THE FATHER OF A
YOUNG GIRL WHO SURVIVED WAS JUST
TRYING TO PROCESS IT ALL.
>> IT WAS SHOCKING.
I GOT THE CALL AT WORK THIS
MORNING.
I CAN'T BELIEVE A SMALL TOWN
LIKE THIS WOULD EVER HAVE
ANYTHING LIKE THIS HAPPEN.
AND TO BE IN AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, THAT'S UNHEARD OF.
>> Reporter: BY LATE FRIDAY
AFTERNOON AND INTO THE EVENING,
EVACUATED CHILDREN WERE BEING
CARED FOR AND REUNITING WITH
THEIR PARENTS AT A NEARBY FIRE
HOUSE.
BRIAN TODD, CNN, WASHINGTON.
>>> SUSAN CANDIOTTI HAS JOINED
ME IN CONNECTICUT, NEWTOWN.
SUSAN, YOU'VE BEEN INVESTIGATING
WHAT HAPPENED, YOU'RE GETTING
NEW INFORMATION.
UPDATE OUR VIEWERS.
>> ALL RIGHT.
FIRST THING THAT IS NEW, WE WANT
TO TALK ABOUT, ARE THE THREE
GUNS THAT WE'VE ALREADY BEEN
IDENTIFYING.
THE GLOCK, THE SIG SAUER, AND
THE BUSHMASTER, THAT UP UNTIL
NOW WE HAVE REPORTED THAT THAT
SEMIAUTOMATIC BUSHMASTER WAS
FOUND IN THE MOTHER'S CAR
BELONGED -- THAT THE SHOOTER WAS
USING PARKED OUTSIDE THE SCHOOL.
NEW INFORMATION IS THAT ALL
THREE OF THOSE GUNS WERE INSIDE,
NEXT TO THE SHOOTER IN THE
CLASSROOM.
IT IS UNCLEAR WHETHER THERE WAS
ANOTHER WEAPON FOUND AT THE
CRIME SCENE SOMEWHERE ELSE.
>> IN ADDITION TO THOSE THREE?
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
HOWEVER, WE DO HAVE THIS NEW
INFORMATION.
AUTHORITIES ARE TRACING THREE
MORE GUNS THAT THE SHOOTER MAY
HAVE HAD ACCESS TO.
WE'RE DOING A FULL TRACE ON ALL
OF THESE GUNS.
THE THREE ADDITIONAL GUNS ARE
DESCRIBED BY LAW ENFORCEMENT
SOURCES AS SINGLE-ACTION RIFLES
OF VARIOUS CALIBERS.
SO THEY ARE CONDUCTING, WE HAVE
THE MAKES AND MODELS.
THEY ARE CONDUCTING A FULL TRACE
TO SEE WHETHER THEY BELONG TO
THE MOTHER, WHERE THEY BELONG TO
THE FATHER, WHETHER THEY MIGHT
HAVE BELONGED TO BOTH.
BUT AUTHORITIES INCLUDING BUREAU
OF ALCOHOL, TOBACCO, AND
FIREARMS, IS CURRENTLY DOING A
TRACE ON THESE WEAPONS.
THEY'RE ALSO LOOKING AT VARIOUS
SPORTING GOODS STORES, GUN
RANGES, THIS KIND OF THING, TO
FIND OUT WHETHER THE SHOOTER IN
THIS CASE VISITED ANY OF THOSE
PLACES.
IN FACT, ANOTHER SOURCE TELLS ME
THAT THEY HAVE INFORMATION THAT
THE SHOOTER MAY HAVE TRIED TO
PURCHASE A WEAPON BUT WAS
UNSUCCESSFUL ON TUESDAY OF THIS
YEAR.
TRIED TO BUY A GUN BUT WAS
UNABLE TO DO SO.
>> BECAUSE OF A BACKGROUND CHECK
OR WHATEVER?
>> I AM TOLD HE DIDN'T HAVE A
PROPER PERMIT.
AND REMEMBER, HE WAS 20 YEARS
OLD.
NOW THAT MIGHT MEAN THAT HE HAD
A FAKE I.D. AT THE TIME, BUT I'M
TOLD THAT HE DIDN'T HAVE THE
PROPER PERMIT IN ADDITION TO
WHAT OTHER SPECIFICATIONS HE
DIDN'T HAVE OR REQUIREMENTS, AND
HE DIDN'T WANT TO WAIT.
>> AS YOU KNOW, THERE ARE
REPORTS HE DID HAVE HIS OLDER
BROTHER'S I.D. ON HIS BODY,
24-YEAR-OLD RYAN LANZA.
THAT WAS -- APPARENTLY THE
RESULT, CAUSING THAT YOU WILL
CONFUSION WHO SHOOTER SERVICE
ORIGINALLY.
HE DID HAVE SOME I.D. ON HIS
BODY THAT SUGGESTED HE WAS RYAN
AS OPPOSED TO ADAM LANZA.
>> THERE ARE REPORTS ABOUT THAT,
AND CERTAINLY IF THAT IS THE
CASE, THAT MIGHT BE AN
EXPLANATION FOR HIM GOING INTO A
GUN STORE AND TRYING TO MAKE A
PURCHASE.
>> DO WE KNOW IF THE THREE
WEAPONS THAT THEY WERE
DISCOVERED INSIDE THE SCHOOL,
THE BUSHMASTER, GLOCK, THE SIG
SAUER, WERE THEY ALL FIRED?
WERE THEY ALL USED?
>> I'VE BEEN UNABLE TO CONFIRM
THAT, BUT I DID ASK THIS --
WHICH ONE OF THOSE HE USED TO
COMMIT SUICIDE.
AND I WAS TOLD THEY DO KNOW BUT
THEY WILL NOT REVEAL THAT AT
THIS TIME.
>> WAS THERE A LOT OF AMMUNITION
THAT WAS STILL USABLE ON THE
SCENE OR DID HE GO THROUGH ALL
THE BULLETS?
>> I'VE BEEN ASKING THAT
QUESTION AND I DON'T HAVE AN
ANSWER TO THAT.
AS YOU KNOW, THEY'RE CURRENTLY
STILL WORKING THAT CRIME SCENE,
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT HOW MANY
BULLET WERE FIRED, IF THERE WAS
ADDITIONAL AMMO.
THOSE ARE IMPORTANT QUESTIONS
AND CERTAINLY ONE THAT
INVESTIGATORS EITHER KNOW AND
AREN'T REVEALING OR ARE STILL
LOOKING INTO.
>> I THINK THEY KNOW A LOT MORE
THAN THEY'RE REVEALING NOW.
TO THEIR CREDIT, THEY WANT TO BE
PRECISE.
THEY DON'T WANT TO GIVE
INFORMATION THAT THEY HAVE TO
LATER WALK BACK AND -- I ADMIRE
THEM FOR DOING THAT.
>> TRYING TO BE VERY CAREFUL.
>> THIS IS OBVIOUSLY A TRAGEDY
THAT HAS SO RESONATED NOT ONLY
IN CONNECTICUT BUT ALL OVER THE
COUNTRY, INDEED ALL OVER THE
WORLD RIGHT NOW.
THEY WANT TO BE -- TO BE
PRECISE.
WE'LL GET MORE INFORMATION.
ARE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
TAKING THE LEAD?
>> THEY ARE, BUT THEY'VE
ACKNOWLEDGED THEY'RE GETTING A
LOT OF COOPERATION FROM THE FBI,
FROM THE ATF, AND ANY OTHER
AGENCIES THEY'RE ASKING.
THEY'RE GETTING IT, AND IT'S
HELPING ADVANCE WHAT THEY'RE
DOING.
>> SUSAN CANDIOTTI, WOKKING HER
SOURC
-- WORKING HER SOURCES, GETTING
INFORMATION.
TO REPEAT THE HEADLINE, ALL
THREE WEAPONS WERE FOUND INSIDE
BECAUSE ORIGINALLY WE THOUGHT
THE RIFLE WAS STILL IN THE
VEHICLE THAT THIS INDIVIDUAL
DROVE TO THE SCHOOL.
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
AND THAT HE MAY HAVE HAD ACCESS
TO THREE ADDITIONAL GUNS.
>> THERE MAY HAVE BEEN -- WE
DON'T KNOW HOW HE GOT THEM, BUT
WE KNOW THE THREE THAT WERE
FOUND WERE REGISTERED IN HIS
MOTHER'S NAME.
>> THAT IS CORRECT.
SHE OWNED THEM.
>> SUSAN, THANKS VERY, VERY
MUCH.
THIS TRAGEDY IS DIFFICULT FOR
ALL OF US TO GRASP.
FOR CHILDREN, IT IS SO, SO
CONFUSING, SO SAD, IT IS
OBVIOUSLY DOWN RIGHT SCARY.
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN TO YOUR KIDS
WHAT HAPPENED WHEN THEY ASK?
CNN'S LISA SYLVESTER BRINGS US
SOME EXPERT ADVICE.
>> Reporter: IF THERE'S AN
EMERGENCY THAT SUMS UP THIS
STORY IT IS -- ANY PARENT CAN
RELATE.
PSYCHOLOGIST CHARLES RAISIN IS
WITH THE UNIVERSITY OF ARIZONA'S
COLLEGE OF MEDICINE.
>> HOW DO YOU WRAP YOUR MIND
AROUND SOMETHING LIKE THIS?
WITH A GOOD DEAL OF HEARTBREAK
AND WITH THE UNDERSTANDING THAT
IT'S GOING TO TAKE A WHILE, AND
THAT THERE WILL BE PEOPLE THAT
WERE CLOSELY IMPACTED BY THIS
WHO WILL NEVER WRAP THEIR MINDS
AROUND THIS.
YOU KNOW, THE HUMAN MINDS ARE
NOT INFINITE.
THIS IS NOW APPEARING TO BE
PROBABLY THE WORCESTST SCHOOL Y
CATASTROPHE IN HISTORY.
THERE'S GOING TO BE A HUGE
LONG-TERM FALLOUT THAT WILL
IMPACT PEOPLE'S EMOTIONAL
WELL-BEING.
WE NEED TO GEAR OURSELVES UP FOR
THAT FALLOUT BECAUSE IT'S
COMING.
THIS IS A HORRIBLE THING.
>> Reporter: THE NEWS OUT OF
NEWTOWN IS TRAUMATIC FOR PARENTS
AND FOR CHILDREN.
THIS HAPPENED AT A SCHOOL WHERE
KIDS ARE SUPPOSED TO FEEL SAFE.
>> HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN THIS TO
DINNER?
AGAIN, IT DEPENDS ON THE AGE --
TO CHILDREN?
AGAIN, IT DEPENDS ON THE AGE OF
THE CHILD.
I THINK EFFORTRIGHT FORTHRIGHT .
WHAT I TELL CHILDREN IS SOMEWHAT
THAT THERE ARE BAD PEOPLE IN THE
WORLD AND SOMETIMES BAD PEOPLE
DO TERRIBLE THINGS.
A TERRIBLE THING HAS HAPPENED,
AND THERE HAVE BEEN CHILDREN
KILLED.
THIS IS TERRIBLE, BUT YOU'RE
SAFE.
AND, YOU KNOW, YOU'RE SAFE AND
YOU'RE IN A SITUATION NOW WHERE
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO BE HARMED.
>> Reporter: THE AMERICAN
ACADEMY OF PEDIATRICS OFFERS
THIS ADVICE -- TAKE INTO ACCOUNT
THE AGE OF THE CHILD AND PROVIDE
BASIC INFORMATION WITHOUT
OFFERING DETAILS THAT MAY ONLY
ALARM THEM.
ASK YOUR CHILDREN WHAT THEY
ALREADY KNOW AND ANSWER
QUESTIONS.
PARENTS CAN SHARE THEIR OWN
FEELINGS AND THE WAYS THEY'RE
COPING.
AND FIND MEANINGFUL WAYS TO HELP
OTHERS.
>> CHILDREN ARE RESILIENT, AND
WHAT REALLY MATTERS NOW IS HOW
WE HELP THEM UNDERSTAND WHAT'S
HAPPENED BUT EVEN I THINK MORE
IMPORTANT, THE SENSE OF
PROTECTION AND SAFETY THAT WE
GIVE THEM STARTING THIS MOMENT
AND FOR THE NEXT WEEKS AND
MONTHS.
>> Reporter: FOR THOSE WHO
WITNESS ED
WITNESSED, THOSE CHILDREN WHO
COVERED THEIR EYES AND EARS TO
SHUT OUT THE HORROR, THEY NEED
TIME, LOVE, AND PRAYERS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID IT, THAT
PARENTS ARE GOING TO GO HOME,
HUG THEIR CHILDREN.
EVEN TO PROCESS THIS AS A
NATION, THAT'S JUST GOING TO
TAKE TIME.
>> LISA SYLVESTER REPORTING FOR
US.
WHAT A POWERFUL, POWERFUL STORY
WITH SOME IMPORTANT ADVICE FOR
ALL OF US.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE MUCH MORE ON
WHAT'S GOING ON IN THIS
INVESTIGATION, THE INVESTIGATION
CONTINUING IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
LET'S CHECK BACK WITH DEBORAH
FEYERICK FOR A LOOK AT SOME OF
THE OTHER TOP STORIES THIS HOUR.
DEB?
>> A QUICK LOOK.
CHECKING SOME OF THE OTHER NEWS
THIS HOUR, TWO PEOPLE ARE DEAD
IN AN APPARENT MURDER/SUICIDE AT
THE EXCALIBUR HOTEL AND CASINO
IN LAS VEGAS.
THE FEMALE VICTIM IS BEING
DESCRIBED AS A VENDOR WORKING AT
THE CONCIERGE DESK.
THE MALE SHOOTER IS BELIEVED TO
HAVE DIED OF A SELF-INFLICTED
GUNSHOT WOUND.
>>> IN EGYPT, PRESIDENT MOHAMED
MORSI CAST HIS BALLOT TODAY FOR
A NEW DRAFT CONSTITUTION.
VOTERS THERE ARE DECIDING
WHETHER THE CONTROVERSIAL
DOCUMENT GOES INTO EFFECT.
THE DAYS LEADING UP TO TODAY'S
VOTE HAVE BEEN MARRED BY MANY
PROTESTS AND LOTS OF VIOLENCE.
>>> IN THE U.K. A MASS WAS HELD
FOR THE NURSE WHO APPARENTLY
HANGED HERSELF FOLLOWING A PRANK
CALL.
HER HUSBAND AND CHILDREN SPOKE
PUBLICLY ABOUT THEIR LOSS FOR
THE FIRST TIME SINCE HER DEATH.
JACINTHA SALDANA TOOK THE HOAX
GRADUAL TWO AUSTRALIAN D.J.s
REGARDING PRINCE WILLIAM'S
PREGNANT WIFE CATHERINE.
THE NURSE'S FUNERAL WILL BE HELD
ON SUNDAY IN SOUTHERN INDIA.
BACK TO YOU.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
LET'S GET TO THE LATEST
DEVELOPMENTS NOW ON THIS MASS
SHOOTING HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW AS OF RIGHT
NOW -- THE BODIES OF ALL 26
VICTIMS, 20 OF THEM CHILDREN,
SIX ADULTS, HAVE NOW BEEN TAKEN
OUT OF THE SMALL ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, TRANSPORTED TO THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER'S OFFICE.
INVESTIGATORS WILL REMAIN AT THE
SCHOOL, THOUGH, FOR THE NEXT DAY
OR TWO, AT THE LEAST GATHERING
MORE EVIDENCE.
THE SHOOTER IDENTIFIED AS
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA FORCED
HIS WAY INTO THE SCHOOL.
BUT THEY'RE NOT REVEALING
EXACTLY HOW HE GOT IN.
POLICE ALSO SAY THEY FOUND WHAT
THEY DESCRIBE AS -- I'M QUOTING
NOW -- GOOD EVIDENCE ABOUT HOW
AND WHY LANZA CARRIED OUT THIS
DEADLY RAMPAGE.
THEY SAY THEY DISCOVERED THAT
INFORMATION AT THE SKOOSHLCHOOL
SECO
SECONDIAARY LOCATION, THE LANZA
HOME WHERE THE MOTHER WAS FOUND
SHOT TO DEATH.
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE SAY ALL
OF THE VICTIMS HAVE BEEN REMOVED
FROM THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL EVEN
THOUGH WE KNOW -- WE DON'T KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED INSIDE,
INVESTIGATORS ARE PAINSTAKINGLY
RE-CREATING THE CRIME SCENE FROM
BEGINNING TO END TO MAKE SURE WE
KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON.
HLN'S LAW ENFORCEMENT ANALYST
MIKE BROOKS IS JOINING US,
DEBORAH FEYERICK STILL WITH US.
MIKE, THESE PEOPLE ARE
PROFESSIONALS, INVESTIGATORS,
THEY HAVE TO DO THIS EXTREMELY
DIFFICULT WORK TO RE-CREATE IN
EFFECT EVERY ONE OF THOSE
MINUTES IF NOT SECONDS OF WHAT
UNFOLDED.
WALK US THROUGH WHAT THEY ARE
DOING NOW AND WHY THEY'RE DOING
IT.
>> YOU HEARD FROM LIEUTENANT
VANCE OF THE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE THAT THEY WILL BE THERE
AT THE SCHOOL AT LEAST FOR
ANOTHER DAY AND A HALF, TWO
DAYS.
EVEN MORE IF THEY NEED THAT
TIME.
WE KNOW THAT THE BODIES HAVE
BEEN REMOVED.
THEY ARE UNDERGOING AUTOPSY AT
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER'S OFFICE.
THAT EVIDENCE WILL BE ANALYZED
BY A CRIME LAB.
BUT BACK AT THE SCHOOL, YOU
STILL HAVE CRIME TEAM -- CRIME
SCENE TECHNICIANS.
YOU SAID THEY HAVE THREE MAJOR
CASE SQUADS THAT ARE GOING OVER
THAT SCHOOL WITH A FINE TOOTH
COMB, BOTH INSIDE AND OUTSIDE.
WOLF, WE DON'T KNOW EXACTLY HOW
MANY ROUNDS WERE FIRED IN THAT
SCHOOL.
WE'RE HEARING WITNESS ACCOUNTS
OF MAYBE 100 OR MORE.
AND NOW THAT MAKES SENSE WITH
THE NEW INFORMATION SUSAN
CANDIOTTI HAS THAT THAT .223
BU
BUSHMASTER WAS INSIDE WITH THE
MAGAZINES WITH 30 ROUNDS EACH.
SO ALL THOSE ROUNDS, THEY WILL
TRY TO ACCOUNT FOR EVERY ONE OF
THOSE ROUNDS, WOLF.
AND THEY WILL TRY TO RE-CREATE
THROUGH STILL PICTURES AND VI  O
VIDEO, FINGERPRINT, DNA, WHAT
HAPPENED.
WE KNOW THE SCHOOL UPGRADED
THEIR SECURITY SYSTEM AND HAD A
SURVEILLANCE CAMERA AT THE FRONT
DOOR.
THE OTHER QUESTION IS, WERE
THERE SURVEILLANCE CAMERAS
THROUGHOUT THE SCHOOL?
IF THERE WAS, THAT WILL ALSO
HELP THEM RE-CREATE WHAT
HAPPENED, RE-CREATE THE TIME
LINE FROM WHEN HE DROVE UP,
FORCED HIS WAY INTO THE SCHOOL,
TO THE TIME HE WENT THROUGH THE
SCHOOL JUST WREAKING HAVOC WITH
THOSE THREE WEAPONS.
>> POLICE SAY THEY NOW SAY THEY
KNOW FOR A FACT HE DID FORCE HIS
WAY INTO THAT SCHOOL.
HE WAS DETERMINED TO GET INSIDE
THAT SMALL ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND
START KILLING PEOPLE.
THE QUESTION IS WHY WOULD ANYONE
WANT TO DO THAT.
WE DON'T HAVE ANY ANSWERS,
ALTHOUGH THE POLICE SAY, MIKE,
THEY HAVE A PRETTY GOOD IDEA OF
WHY HE DID THIS.
WHEN THEY SAY THAT, WHAT DOES
THAT SAY TO YOU?
>> THAT SAYS THAT THEY HAVE
GLEANED SOME INFORMATION FROM
EITHER THERE AT THE SCHOOL, HIS
CAR, THE SECONDARY CRIME SCENE
WHERE HIS MOTHER WAS FOUND DEAD,
OR POSSIBLY ALSO THE INTERVIEWS
THAT THEY'VE DONE WITH ALL OF
HIS FRIENDS, HIS ASSOCIATES.
WE KNOW THAT IN HOBOKEN, NEW
JERSEY, HIS BROTHER RYAN WAS
TAKEN INTO CUSTODY FOR A WHILE
YESTERDAY AND QUESTIONED.
AND POSSIBLY A COMPUTER TAKEN
FROM HIS APARTMENT.
AND HIS FATHER, I'M SURE HE WAS
ABLE TO GIVE A PRETTY GOOD
BACKGROUND, WOLF.
AND THE SECONDARY CRIME SCENE AT
THE HOUSE, THERE COULD HAVE
BEEN.
THEY WENT OVER THAT HOUSE, I
GUARANTEE YOU, WITH A FINE TOOTH
COMB, TAKING ANY COMPUTERS, ANY
LAPTOPS, YOU NAME IT, TO TRY TO
GET INFORMATION ON THE HOW AND
THE WHY ALL THIS HAPPENED.
AND I THINK THAT WE'RE PROBABLY
GOING TO HEAR OVER THE NEXT WEEK
EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED BECAUSE
I'M SURE THAT THEY HAVE GOOD
INFORMATION.
>> DEB, LIKE ME, ALL OF US,
WE'VE COVERED WAY TOO MANY OF
THOSE HORRIFIC, HORRIFIC
TRAGEDIES.
AND UNFORTUNATELY AFTER EACH ONE
WE HOPE THAT IT'S THE LAST BUT
WE KNOW THERE WILL BE MORE
TRAGEDIES DOWN THE ROAD.
I KNOW YOU WANT TO ASK MIKE A
QUESTION.
>> AND THERE'S SO MANY QUESTIONS
THAT HAVE TO BE ANSWERED PEOPLE
SAY, WELL, WHAT WAS THE MOTIVE?
WILL THERE BE A MOTIVE.
AND TO A LOT OF THE FAMILIES,
IT'S PROBABLY LIKE, WELL, IT
DOESN'T MATTER WHETHER THERE'S A
MOTIVE.
MY CHILD IS DEAD.
THE BODIES ARE NOW WITH THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER.
HOW LONG, MIKE, DOES THE PROCESS
TAKE BEFORE THE BODIES ARE
TURNED OVER TO THE FAMILIES, AND
WHEN YOU DO FRIENDS ACTIVITIES A
CHILD, A VICTIM, AN -- FORENSICS
ON A CHILD, A VICTIM, AN ADULT,
IS THERE A TIMELINE?
>> YOU HAVE TO DETERMINE THE
CAUSE OF DEATH.
THE MANNER IS MOST LIKELY
HOMICIDE IN THIS CASE.
BY LAW THEY HAVE TO FILL OUT A
DEATH CERTIFICATE.
IT'S NOT A PLEASANT THING TO
TALK ABOUT, BUT THEY HAVE TO
FILL OUT A DEATH CERTIFICATE FOR
EACH OF THE CHILDREN AND ADULT
KILLED AT THE SCENE AS WELL AS
THE SHOOTER.
AND SO THEY'RE GOING TO GO
THROUGH AN AUTOPSY LIKE THEY
WOULD FORRIN ELS IANYONE ELSE.
THEY HAVE ASKED FOR HELP FROM A
MEDICAL EXAMINER WITHIN THE
STATE OR OUTSIDE THE STATE TO
ASSIST BECAUSE OF THE SHEER
NUMBER OF BODIES.
WHEN YOU HAVE 27, YOU KNOW, 26,
27 BODIES, IT TAKES A LONG TIME
TO DO THAT.
TO DO A THOROUGH JOB.
BUT AS T'S SOMETHING TH-- BUT I
THEY HAVE TO DO, NOT A PLEASANT
TASK BUT SOMETHING THEY HAVE TO
DO.
>> SURE, BUT EVEN AS MANY GUNS
AS THERE ARE, YOU GET THE SENSE
THAT IF SOMEBODY WANTS TO DO
SOMETHING LIKE THIS, SADLY AND
TRAGICALLY THEY'RE GOING TO.
WOLF?
>> YEAH.
IF THEY'RE DETERMINED TO START
KILLING LITTLE CHILDREN IN AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, HOW DO YOU
PREVENT THAT?
AND THAT'S A QUESTION THAT'S
GOING TO BE ASKED.
MIKE, WE'LL CONTINUE THIS
CONVERSATION, STAND BY FOR THAT.
MEANWHILE A COUNTRY AND
PRESIDENT GRIEVING FOR VICTIMS
OF THIS HORRIFIC, HORRIFIC
TRAGEDY.
WE'LL CONTINUE OUR SPECIAL
COVERAGE RIGHT AFTER THIS.
>>> SHOCK AND SADNESS ACROSS THE
NATION, INDEED SO MUCH OF THE
WORLD FOLLOWING A MASS SHOOTING
AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, A FEW
HOURS AFTER THE RAMPAGE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA DELIVERED A
STATEMENT, A POWERFUL STATEMENT
ON THIS HORRIFIC TRAGEDY.
HE GOT VERY EMOTIONAL, SOMETIMES
-- TYPICALLY DOESN'T GET THAT
EMOTIONAL AT LEAST IN PUBLIC,
BUT HE ACTUALLY STARTED TO TEAR
UP AS HE SPOKE ABOUT THESE YOUNG
VICTIMS.
WANT TO PLAY IN ITS ENTIRETY THE
STATEMENT THAT THE PRESIDENT
MADE.
>> THIS AFTERNOON I SPOKE WITH
GOVERNOR MALLOY AND FBI DIRECTOR
MUELLER.
I OFFERED GOVERNOR MALLOY MY
CONDOLENCES ON BEHALF OF THE
NATION AND MADE IT CLEAR HE WILL
HAVE
CONDOLENCES AND WILL GIVE HIM
EVERY RESOURCE HE NEEDS TO
INVESTIGATE THIS CRIME, CARE FOR
THE VICTIMS, COUNSEL THEIR
FAMILIES.
WE'VE ENDURED TOO MANY OF THESE
TRAGEDIES IN THE PAST FEW YEARS
AND EACH TIME I LEARN THE NEWS I
REACT NOT AS A PRESIDENT BUT AS
ANYBODY ELSE WOULD, AS A PARENT.
AND THAT WAS ESPECIALLY TRUE
TODAY.
I KNOW THERE IS NOT A PARENT IN
AMERICA WHO DOES NOT FEEL THE
OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM, BIRTHDAYS,
GRADUATIONS, WEDDINGS, KIDS OF
THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS, MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES TO HELPING
OUR CHILDREN FULFILL THEIR
DREAMS.
SO OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN TODAY.
FOR THE PARENT AND GRANDPARENTS,
SISTERS AND BROTHERS OF THESE
LITTLE CHILDREN AND FOR THE
FAMILIES OF THE ADULTS WHO WERE
LOST.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN FOR THE
PARENT OF THE SURVIVORS AS WELL.
FOR AS BLESSED AS THEY ARE TO
HAVE THEIR CHILDREN HOME
TONIGHT, THEY KNOW THAT THEIR
CHILDREN'S INNOCENCE HAS BEEN
TORN AWAY FROM THEM TOO EARLY
AND THERE ARE NO WORDS THAT WILL
EASE THEIR PAIN.
AS A COUNTRY, WE HAVE BEEN
THROUGH THIS TOO MANY TIMES,
WHETHER IT'S AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN OR A SHOPPING
MALL IN OREGON OR A TEMPLE IN
WISCONSIN OR A MOVIE THEATER IN
AURORA OR A STREET CORNER IN
CHICAGO, THESE NEIGHBORHOODS ARE
OUR NEIGHBORHOODS AND THESE
CHILDREN ARE OUR CHILDREN.
AND WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO COME
TOGETHER AND TAKE MEANINGFUL
ACTION TO PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS REGARDLESS OF THE
POLITICS.
THIS EVENING, MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT
IN AMERICA WILL DO, WHICH IS HUG
OUR CHILDREN TIGHTER AND REMIND
EACH OTHER HOW DEEPLY WE LOVE
ONE ANOTHER BUT THERE ARE FA
FAMILIES IN CONNECTICUT WHO
CANNOT DO THAT AND THEY NEED US
RIGHT NOW TO COME TOGETHER AS
AMERICANS AND I WILL DO
EVERYTHING IN MY POWER AS
PRESIDENT TO HELP BECAUSE WHILE
NOTHING CAN FILL THE SPACE OF
THE LOT OF CHILD S LOST CHILD O
ALL OF US CAN REMIND THEM THAT
WE ARE THERE FOR THEM, THAT WE
ARE PRAYING FOR THEM, THAT THE
LOVE THEY FELT FOR THOSE THEY
LOST ENDURES NOT JUST IN THEIR
MEMORIES BUT ALSO IN OURS.
MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORIES OF
THE VICTIMS AND IN THE WORDS OF
SCRIPTURE, HEAL THE
BROKENHEARTED AND BIND UP THEIR
WOUNDS.
>> NOT OFTEN YOU SEE A PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED STATES WIPING AWAY
TEARS, HOLDING BACK THOSE TEARS,
SPEAKING SO EMOTIONALLY, SO
PERSONALLY, NOT ONLY AS THE
PRESIDENT BUT ALSO AS A FATHER.
IN THAT INITIAL STATEMENT HE
DIDN'T DIRECTLY ADDRESS THE VERY
SENSITIVE ISSUE OF GUN CONTROL
IN THE UNITED STATES.
BUT THE WHITE HOUSE PRESS
SECRETARY JAY CARNEY DID TELL
REPORTERS THE PRESIDENT SUPPORTS
REINSTATING A FEDERAL BAN ON THE
ASSAULT ON ASSAULT WEAPONS.
THAT WAS FROM THE WHITE HOUSE
PRESS SECRETARY, JAY CARNEY.
THE HARROWING WORDS FROM THE
STUDENTS WHO WITNESSED SOMETHING
THAT NO CHILD SHOULD EVER HAVE
TO SEE ARE SUCH A POWERFUL
REMINDER OF THE ENORMITY OF THIS
TRAGEDY.
TO GIVE US A BETTER IDEA OF WHAT
HAPPENED, CNN JOSH LEVS IS GOING
TO GIVE US A 3-D LOOK AT THE
SCHOOL.
>> I'M GOING TO TAKE YOU THROUGH
SOME NEW INFORMATION THAT WE GOT
THIS MORNING.
THIS IS A 3-D IMAGE OF THE
SCHOOL.
WE LEARNED THIS MORNING THAT
POLICE ARE SAYING THAT THE
ENTIRE THING IS AND REMAINS A
CRIME SCENE.
THEY SAY THEY ARE SEARCHING EACH
AND EVERY ROOM AND IN THE WORDS
OF THE POLICE, EACH HE EVERY
WEEK IN THE PARKING LOT.
WE DO NOT KNOW IF THERE ARE
SPECIFIC THINGS THEY ARE LOOKING
FOR BUT WE DO KNOW THAT THEY ARE
SEARCHING ABSOLUTELY EVERYTHING,
SCOURING THE AREA.
POLICE PUT OUT A STATEMENT THIS
MORNING SAYING THAT THE FIRST
911 CALL ABOUT THIS CAME IN AT
ABOUT 9:30 A.M.
I WANT OUR VIEWERS IN THIS
COUNTRY AND AROUND THE WORLD TO
UNDERSTAND THAT EVERY SECONDS
COUNT, EVEN FRACTIONS OF A
MINUTE.
IF THE CALL CAME IN AROUND 9:30
A.M., THAT PUTS THE TIME FRAME
BACK FROM TEN MINUTES FROM WHAT
WE BELIEVED LAST NIGHT AND THAT
CAN INTRODUCE NEW QUESTIONS.
WHEN SCHOOL WAS BEGINNING, WAS
THE GUNMAN ALREADY THERE?
WAS HE HIDING IN PLACES?
WAS THERE SOMETHING THAT SOMEONE
COULD HAVE SEEN MIGHT HAVE
ULTIMATELY MADE A DIFFERENCE?
LET ME TALK YOU THROUGH A LITTLE
BIT ABOUT WHAT WE'VE BEEN
HEARING ABOUT THIS ACTUAL
ATTACK.
WE DO KNOW NOW THAT THIS GUNMAN
FORCED HIS WAY INTO THE
BUILDING.
THERE'S A SECURITY SYSTEM AT
THIS BUILDING.
WE DON'T KNOW EXACTLY HOW HE DID
BUT ONE OF THE CHIEF QUESTIONS
THAT SCHOOL AROUND THE COUNTRY,
PEOPLE WILL BE ASKING, HOW DOES
SOMEONE FORCE THEMSELVES INTO
THE SCHOOL WITH A WEAPON?
WE HEARD SOMETHING THAT CAN TURN
OUT TO BE VERY SIGNIFICANT.
IT'S BELIEVED THAT THIS AREA
RIGHT HERE IS WHERE THE
SHOOTINGS TOOK PLACE AND THAT
THE WEAPONS WERE FOUND RIGHT
NEAR HIM.
BUT WE HAVE TO FIND OUT EXACTLY
WHAT HAPPENED STEP BY STEP
INSIDE THIS SCHOOL AND WHAT
POTENTIAL EVIDENCE THAT MIGHT
OTHERWISE -- OR ULTIMATELY END
UP FINDING AT ANY PART INSIDE
THAT SCHOOL, WOLF.
I ALSO WANT TO MENTION, THERE
WERE WINDOWS BROKEN AROUND THE
SCHOOL AND THAT LEADS PEOPLE TO
BELIEVE THAT MAYBE THIS GUNMAN
BROKE ONE OF THE WINDOWS TO GET
IN.
POLICE SAID, DON'T JUMP TO THAT
C
CONCLUSION.
WHEN AUTHORITIES ARRIVED TO
RESPOND, THEY HAD TO FORCE THEIR
WAY IN.
THAT INVOLVED BREAKING WINDOWS.
SO, AGAIN, NEW QUESTIONS ABOUT
ALL THAT.
AND, FOLKS, WHILE I DO THIS, I
WANT TO REMIND YOU ALL, I'M
PUTTING MY HANDS ALL OVER THIS
AS IF IT'S A CRIME SCENE BUT
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT A CHILDREN'S
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, SOMETHING
THAT SHOULD NEVER, EVER BE A
CRIME SCENE.
WOLF, I'M A FATHER, YOU ARE A
FATHER AND PEOPLE ALL AROUND THE
WORLD ARE SHARING THIS HORROR
RIGHT THERE WITH US.
>> SUCH A POWERFUL, POWERFUL
REMINDER OF THE FRAGILE NATURE
OF OUR SOCIETY AND YOU GO TO --
YOU TAKE YOUR KIDS TO ASK SCHOOL
IN THE MORNING AND YOU NEVER,
EVER, EVER SHOULD HAVE TO EXPECT
ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
>> THAT'S WHAT WE'RE ALL
GRAPPLING WITH.
>> JOSH, THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR
THAT REPORT.
>> SURE.
>>> WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A QUICK
BREAK.
OUR SPECIAL COVERAGE WILL RESUME
RIGHT AFTER THIS.
OVER FIFTY DOLLARS LESS
THAN BEST BUY!
WOW! FIFTY BUCKS!
YEAH!
THAT'S A PAIR OF SHOES.
SEE FOR YOURSELF IF YOU COULD
SAVE ON THE GIFTS YOU WANT.
WALMART.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
ANY TREE ON THIS LOT
IS ON ME.
I'M THE MESSENGER,
BY THE WAY.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
JOANNE.
WITH THE HUNDREDS THAT I SAVE
WITH PROGRESSIVE
ON MY CAR INSURANCE,
THIS TREE IS ON ME.
NO WAY.
WAY.
THIS TREE IS ON ME.
REALLY?!
YES.
AAH!
LET ME JUST TRIM IT UP
A LITTLE BIT FOR YOU.
[ buzzing ]
THANK YOU.
SAVING'S GREETINGS.
YOU GUYS ARE GONNA GET THIS TREE
RIGHT HERE?
ARE YOU SURE
THAT'S THE ONE?
I'LL TIE IT TO THE ROOF
FOR YOU.
MAKE SAVINGS
A NEW HOLIDAY TRADITION.
♪