>>> FOR MORE INFORMATION, ON HOW
YOU CAN HELP THOSE AFFECTED BY
THE SHOOTING, GO TO
CNN.COM/IMPACT.
>>> HELLO, EVERYONE, I'M DON
LEMON REPORTING LIVE FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, TWO DAYS
AFTER A GUNMAN WENT ON A RAMPAGE
AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THROUGHOUT THE DAY WE'LL BRING
YOU DETAILS ON THE VICTIMS AND
ON THE INVESTIGATION.
AND THERE'S OTHER BIG STORIES
THAT ARE BREAKING TODAY AS WELL
OUR DEBRA FERICK WILL HELP US
GET THROUGH THAT BACK IN
ATLANTA.
WE'LL SEE YOU IN JUST A MOMENT.
BUT FIRST A MASS SHOOTING THATS
HAS CUT SHORT THE LIVES OF 26
PEOPLE, 20 OF THEM CHILDREN.
A CRIME THAT HAS LEFT THIS
COMMUNITY AND THE ENTIRE NATION
IN A STATE OF SHOCK.
IN NEWTOWN, AND SURROUNDING
TOWNS, MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS ARE
BEING SET UP AND VIGILS ARE
BEING HELD FOR THE VICTIMS.
IT IS AN OVERWHELMING OUTPOURING
OF GRIEF, SADNESS AND SUPPORT
FOR THE FAMILIES WHO HAVE LOST
LOVED ONES IN FRIDAY'S MASSACRE.
THERE WAS THIS EMOTIONAL
GATHERING ABOUT 30 MILES AWAY
FROM NEWTOWN IN STRATFORD.
♪
>>> 150 PEOPLE ATTENDED A
CANDLELIGHT VIGIL IN NEWTOWN
LAST NIGHT.
MANY OF THEM WERE SOBBING AS THE
NAMES OF THE VICTIMS WERE READ
OUT LOUD.
PRESIDENT BARACK OBAMA WILL TRY
TO COMFORT THE FAMILIES, HE'S
SCHEDULED TO ARRIVE IN NEWTOWN
IN A COUPLE OF HOURS.
HE'LL MEET WITH FAMILIES AND
FIRST RESPONDERS AND THEN
TONIGHT HE'LL SPEAK AT AN
INTERFAITH VIGIL.
WE'LL BRING YOU THE SERVICE LIVE
TO YOU ON CNN IN ITS ENTIRETY.
7:00 P.M. ON CNN.
NOW TO THE LATEST ON THE
INVESTIGATION, CNN'S ALISON
KOSIK JOINS US WITH NEW
INFORMATION FROM POLICE.
ALLISON?
>> I AM STANDING, DON IN THE
NEIGHBORHOOD WHERE THE GUNMAN,
ADAM LANZA, LIVED WITH HIS
MOTHER, NANCY LANZA, WHO HE
POLICE SAY KILLED BEFORE HE WENT
ON THE MASSACRE AT THE SCHOOL.
NOW WE'RE NOT SURE YET IF THIS
AREA HAS BEEN CLOSED DOWN, AS A
CRIME SCENE.
WE CERTAINLY HAVE NOT SEEN ANY
ACTIVITY HERE SINCE YESTERDAY
AFTERNOON.
YOU KNOW THE FOCUS REALLY SEEMS
TO BE ON THE SCHOOL AT THIS
POINT.
WE'RE LEARNING NEW DETAILS, EVEN
FROM THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT.
DAN MALLOY.
HE CONFIRMED WHAT OUR SOURCES
HAD BEEN TELLING US, THAT THE
GUNMAN LITERALLY BLASTED, HE
SHOT HIS WAY INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
DESPITE THE FACT THAT THE SCHOOL
HAD SECURITY IN PLACE.
THAT YOU HAD TO BE BUZZED IN AS
OF 9:30 TO GET INTO THIS SCHOOL.
BECAUSE THE DOORS WERE LOCKED.
INCLUDING SECURITY CAMERAS
INSIDE THE SCHOOL AS WELL.
BUT ONCE AGAIN, WE'RE LEARNING
THAT HE LITERALLY SHOT HIS WAY
INTO THE SCHOOL.
FROM STATE POLICE, WE'RE ALSO
LEARNING THAT THEY DISCOVERED
FOUR WEAPONS AT THE SCHOOL, THEY
WERE FOUND AT THE SCHOOL.
THREE IN THE CLASSROOM, ANOTHER
ONE WAS FOUND AT THE CRIME
SCENE.
AND AN ADDITIONAL THREE WEAPONS
ARE SOURCES SAY, WERE FOUND IN
THE HOME WHERE ADAM SHARED WITH
HIS MOTHER, NANCY.
AS FOR OTHER DETAILS.
ABOUT THE VICTIMS, THIS BECOMES
VERY HEARTBREAKING WHEN YOU HEAR
THE DETAILS COME OUT.
WE'RE LEARNING THAT ALL OF THE
VICTIMS DIED FROM MULTIPLE
GUNSHOT WOUNDS.
SOME OF THESE LITTLE KIDS, SIX
AND SEVEN YEARS OLD, WERE SHOT
ANYWHERE FROM THREE TO 11 TIMES.
WE'RE ALSO LEARNING THAT THE
GUNMAN SHOT INSIDE THE SCHOOL,
INSIDE A SECTION OF THE SCHOOL.
JUST TWO CLASSROOMS.
AND THE HALLWAY.
AND FROM THIS NEWS CONFERENCE
THAT WE LISTENED TO, A LITTLE
WHILE AGO, DON, WE ALSO LEARNED
THAT THE QUESTION WAS, WILL
THESE KIDS RETURN, WILL THE
CHILDREN RETURN TO THIS SCHOOL
NOW THAT WHAT'S HAPPENED THERE.
AND THE WAY THAT QUESTION WAS
ANSWERED WAS, IT'S TOO EARLY TO
SAY WHETHER OR NOT THAT WOULD
HAPPEN.
BUT IT LOOKS LIKE POSSIBLY THAT
KIDS WILL BE TRANSPORTED TO
ANOTHER SCHOOL IN THE AREA.
AND THAT THEY'RE HOPING, THEY'RE
REALLY HOPING THAT THEY KEEP
THESE KIDS TOGETHER.
AND YOU CAN ONLY UNDERSTAND WHY.
YOU WANT TO KEEP THESE KIDS
TOGETHER WHO HAVE BEEN THROUGH
SUCH A TRAUMATIC, HORRIBLE
EXPERIENCE.
DON?
>> DON'T QUOTE ME ON THAT.
I THINK I HAD A GUEST ON
EARLIER, ALLISON.
I DON'T KNOW IF I HAVE THE RIGHT
SCHOOL DISTRICT.
I THINK SHE SAID THEY'RE GOING
TO BE TRANSFERRED TO MONROE
SCHOOL DISTRICT.
THAT APPEARS TO BE IN THE WORKS.
>>> I ALSO UNDERSTAND THAT YOU
TALKED TO A MAN WHOSE CHILDREN
USED TO GO TO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND HE IS
TRYING TO MOBILIZE HIS NEIGHBORS
TO TAKE ACTION TO PREVENT THESE
KINDS OF TRAGEDIES FROM
HAPPENING TO ANYONE, NOT JUST
KIDS.
>> HIS NAME IS LEE SCHULL.
TALKING TO ME EARLIER, HOW DO
YOU REALLY, YOU KNOW, MAKE SENSE
OF THIS?
HOW DO YOU MOVE FORWARD AFTER
THIS.
HE SAYS YOU KNOW, SOME PEOPLE
GRIEVE.
AND HE SAID WHAT HE WANTS TO DO
IS TAKE ACTION.
SO WHAT HE'S TRIED TO DO TODAY
GET AS MANY PEOPLE TOGETHER,
IN FACT HE'S IN HIS MEETING
RIGHT NOW.
HE GOT A MEETING TOGETHER WITH
PEOPLE WHO LIVED IN NEWTOWN.
TO TRY TO FIGURE OUT WHAT TO DO.
HIS ULTIMATE GOAL IS TO TRY TO
MAKE CHANGE HAPPEN TO TRY TO
FIGURE OUT WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
WHY IT HAPPENED AND TO TRY TO
MAKE CHANGE.
WHETHER IT'S GUN LAWS OR TRYING
TO FIGURE OUT HOW TO CHANGE THE
MORAL FABRIC OF THIS COUNTRY.
HE HAS CERTAINLY GOTTEN PEOPLE
TOGETHER TODAY, AND LISTEN TO
WHY HE'S DOING THIS.
>> WE'RE TRYING TO GET THE WORD
OUT TO THE COUNTRY, WE THOUGHT
THIS WAS A SAFE COMMUNITY BUT IN
ANY COMMUNITY, WHETHER IT'S A
PROLIFERATION OF GUNS AND PEOPLE
WITH MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES,
POSSIBLY, THIS CAN HAPPEN
ANYWHERE.
WE NEED TO START HERE AND TAKE
THIS EVENT AND LEARN FROM IT AND
WE NEED IT TO GROW ACROSS THE
COUNTRY.
>> LEE SHULL LIVES IN THE
NEIGHBORHOOD WHERE THE GUNMAN
LIVED.
HE SAID HE'S FEELING IT EVEN IN
HIS HOME.
EVEN THOUGH HE'S NEVER MET THE
GUNMAN BEFORE.
HE SAID HIS DAUGHTER, WHO WENT
TO THE SCHOOL, WAS AT THE SCHOOL
IN THAT CLASSROOM WHERE ALL OF
THOSE CHILDREN WERE GUNNED DOWN.
HE SAID THREE OTHER GIRLS WHO
SHARE A DANCE STUDIO WITH ONE OF
HIS DAUGHTERS, THEY HAVE BEEN
KILLED.
YOU SEE, YOU SEE HOW THIS
COMMUNITY IS SO CONNECTED AND
WHY SOMEONE LIKE LEE SCHULL
WANTS TO COME OUT AND DO
SOMETHING TO FEEL LIKE HE'S
TRYING TO HELP THE PROCESS
ALONG.
AS THIS COMMUNITY TRIES TO HEAL
FROM SOMETHING THAT FEELS LIKE
IT'S GOING TO BE IMPOSSIBLE TO
HEAL FROM.
DON?
>> YEAH.
A LOT OF PEOPLE HAVE SAID TO ME,
SOME PEOPLE WHO WERE AT THE
SCHOOL.
OTHERS WHO JUST KNOW PEOPLE SAY
AT THIS POINT THEY FEEL
HELPLESS.
AND SO YOU KNOW, HE WANTS TO DO
SOMETHING TO HELP OUT SO HE
DOESN'T FEEL HELPLESS.
I THINK IT'S A NORMAL, NATURAL
FEELING IN THIS SITUATION.
THANK YOU, ALLISON.
WE'LL GET BACK TO YOU LATER ON
THROUGHOUT THE HOUR.
>>> AND FOR MANY PEOPLE,
ESPECIALLY THE FAMILIES OF THE
VICTIMS, YOU KNOW THE BIG
QUESTION IS WHY.
WHY DID A GUNMAN ALLEGEDLY KILL
HIS MOTHER, AND THEN GO TO A
SCHOOL AND KILL INNOCENT
CHILDREN AND ADULTS?
I WANT TO BRING IN JOHN NaVORRO,
A FORMER FILER FOR THE FBI, JOE,
WE DON'T HAVE ANY LETTERS LEFT
BEHIND.
WE DON'T KNOW A MOTIVE.
AS A PROFILER, I WONDER WHERE
YOU BEGIN WHEN SOMEONE, I MEAN
QUITE HONESTLY, MAY HAVE TAKEN
MANY OF THE ANSWERS TO HIS
GRAVE.
>> THAT'S THE UNFORTUNATE THING.
IS WE MAY NOT HAVE ALL THE
ANSWERS.
ONE OF THE THINGS THAT WE'VE
LENARD OVER THE YEARS IS THESE
INDIVIDUALS DON'T ACT JUST ON
IMPULSE.
THIS IS USUALLY SOMETHING THAT'S
BEEN GOING ON FOR A WHILE.
THERE IS SOME PLANNING.
THERE'S THE ACQUISITION OF THE
WEAPONS.
THERE'S OFTENTIMES A LOT OF
WOUND COLLECTING WHERE THEY
FOCUS ON SOCIAL SLIGHTS.
THINGS THAT HAVE BEEN DONE TO
THEM.
THEY NURTURE THESE THINGS AND
THEN THEY USE THAT TO, TO SORT
OF POTENTIATE THEM, SO WHEN THEY
ACT OUT, THEY ACT OUT VIOLENTLY.
>> A LOT OF THESE INDIVIDUALS DO
GIVE OFF CLUES, THEY DO LEAVE
BEHIND IN SOCIAL MEDIA.
SOME INDICATORS.
OFTENTIMES PEOPLE WE TALK TO SAY
BOY, THERE WAS SOMETHING QUIRKY,
ODD, SOMEBODY SHOULD HAVE BEEN
LOOKING AT THIS INDIVIDUAL.
BUT NO ONE LIVES WITH A CAMERA
BEHIND THEM ALL THE TIME.
SO IT'S OFTEN VERY DIFFICULT TO
DETECT.
>> BUT JOE, YOU KNOW, I KNOW A
LOT OF QUIRKY AND ODD PEOPLE.
SOME PEOPLE MAY SAY THAT I AM
QUIRKY AND ODD.
THERE IS -- THERE'S A DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN QUIRKY AND ODD AND GOING
INTO A SCHOOLHOUSE AND YOU KNOW
GUNNING PEOPLE DOWN, ESPECIALLY
CHILDREN.
IT'S ALWAYS, IT SEEMS TO ALWAYS
BE YOUNG MEN IN THEIR 20s.
WHAT'S, WHAT'S UP WITH THAT?
>> WELL THERE'S A LOT OF
THEORIES THAT SAY THIS IS A
TESTOSTERONE ISSUE.
WE DON'T HAVE GIRLS GOING OUT
AND DOING MASS, MASS KILLINGS.
THAT TESTOSTERONE FOSTERS THIS.
BUT OBVIOUSLY NOT EVERYBODY
BECOMES A KILLER.
>> BECAUSE TESTOSTERONE FLOWS IN
THEIR VEINS.
THESE ARE PEOPLE THAT ARE NOT
PROFESSIONALS.
THINK IF PROFESSIONALS LOOKED AT
THESE INDIVIDUALS, THEY WOULD
SAY THERE'S ACTUALLY SOMETHING
HERE THIS INDIVIDUAL IS
HARBORING A LOT OF GRIEF OR THEY
A
ARE.
>> THINKING ABOUT VIOLENCE TO
CORRECT A SITUATION.
>> HEY, JOE, CAN I JUMP IN AND
ASK YOU THIS.
WE ALWAYS SAY THEY'RE HARBORING
GRIEF.
MOST PEOPLE WHO HARBOR GRIEF.
I'VE LOST A NUMBER OF PEOPLE --
PEOPLE HARBOR GRIEF, YOU DON'T
TELL PEOPLE ABOUT IT.
SO NO ONE KNOWS, YOU SORT OF
KEEP IT ON THE INSIDE.
HOW CAN YOU PROFILE THAT?
>> WELL, AND THAT'S THE PROBLEM.
YOU KNOW, THE SECRET SERVICE
LOOKED AT IT.
AT THIS IN 2004.
AND FOUND THAT THERE IS NO TEM
PLA
PLATE.
THERE ARE SOME PEOPLE THAT DO
COLLECT THESE WOUNDS, THEY DO
NURTURE THIS GRIEF.
THAT THEY DO NURTURE THESE
SOCIAL SLIGHTS.
>> THEY BUILD ON THEM AND USE
THEM.
>> MOST OF US DON'T SIT AROUND
AND DEBRIEF OUR CHILDREN.
AND THAT'S WHY, YOU KNOW, TEN
YEARS ON, SINCE COLUMBINE HIGH
SCHOOL, THERE'S REALLY NO
TEMPLATE FOR BEING ABLE TO
DISSECT THIS.
OTHER THAN WE HAVE TO OBSERVE.
AND THEN WHEN WE SENSE THAT
THERE'S ISSUES.
WE HAVE TO TRY TO GET CHILDREN
SOME HELP.
>> YOU BRING UP A VERY GOOD
POINT.
I THINK THAT'S MAYBE OF THE
SOLUTIONS THERE.
WHEN YOU SAY MOST OF US DON'T
SIT AROUND AND DEBRIEF OUR
CHILDREN.
MAYBE WE SHOULD EVERY DAY.
AFTER SCHOOL, HOW WAS YOUR DAY,
WHAT DID YOU DO, HOW ARE YOU
FEELING.
AND IN THE MORNING, SAME THING.
THAT MAY BE PART OF THE
SOLUTION.
THANK YOU, JOE NaVORRO, WE
APPRECIATE IT.
>> THERE'S SOME DEVELOPING NEWS
COMING OUT OF WASHINGTON TO TELL
YOU ABOUT.
HAS HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER
COME UP WITH A PROPOSAL?
THE PRESIDENT AND DEMOATS CAN
ACCEPT TO AVOID THE FISCAL
CLIFF?
WE'VE GOT THE DETAILS.
DTD
♪
...OR YOU CAN GET OUT THERE
WITH YOUR FRIENDS
AND ACTUALLY SHARE SOMETHING.
♪
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON,
OFFERING SOME OF OUR BEST
VALUES OF THE YEAR.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAND.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
♪ OOH BABY,
CAN I DO FOR YOU TODAY? ♪
[ Female Announcer ] NEED HELP
KEEPING YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE?
ALIGN CAN HELP.
ONLY ALIGN HAS BIFANTIS,
A PATENTED PROBIOTIC
THAT NATURALLY HELPS MAINTAIN
YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE.
TRY ALIGN TO HELP RETAIN
A BALANCED DIGESTIVE SYSTEM.
TRY THE #1 GASTROENTEROLOGIST
RECOMMENDED PROBIOTIC.
ALIGN.
AND IT APPEARS THAT PRESIDENT
OBAMA HAS TAPPED MASSACHUSETTS
SENATOR, JOHN KERRY, TO BE HIS
NEXT SECRETARY OF STATE.
A SOURCE SAYS THE PRESIDENT MAY
MAKE THE ANNOUNCEMENT LATER THIS
WEEK.
KERRY NARROWLY LOST THE
PRESIDENCY IN 2004, TO PRESIDENT
GEORGE W. BUSH.
HE IS CHAIRMAN OF THE SENATE
FOREIGN RELATIONS COMMITTEE AND
HE'S ALSO A DECORATED VETERAN OF
THE VIETNAM WAR.
>>> WELL IN CALIFORNIA, A
FRIGHTENING INCIDENT FOR
SHOPPERS AT A MALL PARKING LOT.
NEWPORT BEACH.
[ GUNSHOTS ]
>> THAT IS WHAT YOU'RE HEARING,
A MAN IN THE PARKING LOT FIRED
50 SHOTS IN THE AIR.
STORES FILLED WITH HOLIDAY
SHOPPERS QUICKLY LOCKED THEIR
DOORS, NO ONE WAS HIT BUT ONE
PERSON SUFFERED MINOR INJURIES
TRYING TO GET OUT OF THE AREA.
THE SUSPECT IS IN CUSTODY.
POLICE GAVE NO REASON FOR THE
SHOOTSING.
AND LET'S GO BACK TO DON LEMON
LIVE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
ONE THING I WAS LISTENING TO
YOUR INTERVIEW WITH THE
PROFILER.
WHAT'S SO INCREDIBLE ABOUT THE
ALLEGED SHOOTER.
HE'S LIKE A GHOST.
AFTER COLUMBINE, WE HAD A HUGE
SORT OF BIO ON WHO THESE TWO
KIDS WERE.
AFTER THE MOVIE SHOOTING, THE
ONE THAT YOU COVERED SO
EXTENSIVELY.
WE KNEW A SENSE OF WHO THAT
PERSON WAS.
BUT IN THIS PARTICULAR CASE,
THIS ALLEGED SHOOTER, ADAM
LANZA, HE'S LIKE A GHOST.
NOBODY KNOWS ANYTHING ABOUT HIM.
>> NOTHING ABOUT HIM.
SOME THINGS YOU MAY NOT KNOW AS
YOU HEARD THE PROFILER SAY.
THEY DON'T HAVE INFORMATION ON
PEOPLE WHO HARBOR GRIEF AND
RESENTMENT BECAUSE THEY DON'T
TALK ABOUT IT THAT MUCH.
DEB, BEFORE I MOVE ON.
I WANT TO THANK YOU FOR WHAT YOU
SAID COMING OUT OF THOSE TWO
LADIES WHO WERE HERE.
BECAUSE I'M NOT A PARENT.
I'M AN UNCLE AND A GREAT UNCLE,
THAT'S NOT THE SAME AS BEING A
PARENT.
AND THIS MUST BE REALLY TOUGH
FOR PARENTS AROUND THE COUNTRY,
ESPECIALLY WITH SCHOOL-AGED
CHILDREN RIGHT NOW.
>> IT'S SO DIFFICULT.
BECAUSE THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT
A CHILD, THEY ARE JUST -- YOU
KNOW, WHEN A CHILD TURNS TWO IT
EFFECTIVELY DOUBLES THEIR
LIFESPAN ON THE EARTH.
THERE'S SO MUCH LEARNING AND
THERE'S SO MUCH GROWING THAT
GOES ON EACH AND EVERY YEAR.
THAT IT'S JUST, YOU CAN'T EVEN
IMAGINE IT.
I ONCE REMEMBER HEARING
SOMETHING THAT WAS SO POWERFUL.
THAT AN OAK TREE AND A ROSE BOTH
LIVE THE SAME AMOUNT, THE
LIFETIME THAT THEY ARE SUPPOSED
TO LIVE AND THAT'S THE ONLY WAY
THAT I CAN LOOK AT IT.
WHICH IS YOU KNOW, THE OAK TREE,
WHICH MAY BE 94 YEARS OLD AND A
CHILD THAT'S SIX -- IT'S THE
LIFETIME THAT'S SET FOR THEM.
I SUPPOSE.
>> WELL DEB, THANK YOU FOR THAT
WE APPRECIATE IT AND OUR
THOUGHTS AND PRAYERS ARE WITH
NOT ONLY THE PEOPLE HERE, BUT
ALL THE MOMS AND DADS AROUND THE
COUNTRY WHO ARE HORRIFIED BY
THIS.
DEB, STICK AROUND, WE'LL GET
BACK TO YOU IN ATLANTA.
>>> THE SHOOTINGS IN SANDY HOOK
THRUST THE SMALL TOWN OF NEWTOWN
INTO THE SPOTLIGHT.
WE'LL LOOK AT THE TOWN NEXT.
SO, THIS BOARD
GIVES ME RATES FOR
PROGRESSIVE DIRECT AND OTHER
CAR INSURANCE COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
CALL OR CLICK TODAY.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
>>> NEWTOWN IS A CLOSE-KNIT
COMMUNITY.
SO THE GRIEF OF THIS SCHOOL
SHOOTING IS AFFECTING EVERYONE.
AS CNN'S LAW LAW SHOWS US.
>> IT'S SO SAD HOW QUICKLY ALL
OF THAT CAN BE TAKEN AWAY FROM
YOU IN A HEARTBEAT.
>> GRIEF HAS SETTLED IN FOR THE
PARENTS.
LEAR THAN DO NOTHING, LAURA CAN
LAY FLOWERS AND BE GRATEFUL THAT
HER OWN CHILDREN DON'T SEEM TO
UNDERSTAND.
A LUXURY OF THE VERY YOUNG THAT
MOST DON'T HAVE.
A SMALL COMMUNITY THEY ALL SEEM
TO KNOW A VICTIM.
SOME, DIRECTLY.
>> WE FEEL SOMETHING UNUSUAL.
THEY DIDN'T RESPOND ON THE PHONE
CALLS.
OR MESSAGES.
TWO WORDS.
>> TRYING TO COPE AND CONNECT,
SIGNS ARE EVERYWHERE IN THE TOWN
CENTER.
THIS ONE MARKED EACH LOST
VICTIM.
COUNTING UP TO 27.
INCLUDING THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER.
ANOTHER REMINDED IT WASN'T JUST
CHILDREN WHO WERE LOST.
MANDY IVES IS THINKING OF THE
PRINCIPAL, HER 9-YEAR-OLD SON
WAS A STUDENT AT THE SCHOOL.
>> WE MOVED HERE IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE SCHOOL YEAR.
SHE WAS SO KIND TO MY SON.
>> DAVID KEEN'S 5-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHTER ALEXIS, WENT TO
PRESCHOOL WITH THE CHILDREN OF
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
>> I'M AFRAID TO EVEN LOOK IT
AND RECOGNIZE AND SEE THE NAMES
OF MY LITTLE ONES' PLAYMATES.
KEEN SENT HIS DAUGHTER TO A
DIFFERENT ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
A STROKE OF FATE ON A DAY WHEN
PARENTS LOOK FOR ANSWERS WHERE
THERE ARE NONE.
>> JUST HEARTWRENCHING RIGHT
NOW.
IT'S NOT EASY TO SWALLOW WHAT'S
GOING ON IN MY BACK YARD.
>> KEUNG LAW, CNN, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>>> YESTERDAY, I TOOK A WALK
THROUGH THIS TOWN AND THIS TOWN
OF 27,000 PEOPLE, ALL OF THEM
ARE STILL TRYING TO PROCESS THE
HORROR OF WHAT HAPPENED JUST
DOWN THE ROAD.
THAT'S THE ROAD THAT LEADS UP TO
THE SCHOOL WHERE THIS HAPPENED.
IT'S BEEN BLOCKED OFF.
YOU CAN SEE THE SIGN HERE RIGHT
ACROSS THE STREET ON THE PORCH
IT SAID GOD BLESS SANDY HOOK.
THAT JUST ABOUT SAYS IT ALL.
RIGHT HERE IN THE MIDDLE OF THE
SQUARE, 26 CANDLES.
FOR ALL OF THE VICTIMS IN THE
TRAGEDY RIGHT HERE AT THE TIMES
SQUARE.
AND UP THE STREET, A CHURCH
WHERE THE VICTIMS ARE BEING
MEMORIALIZED.
SO THIS IS ONE OF THE INTIMATE
LITTLE SQUARES HERE IN SANDY
HOOK.
YOU CAN SEE THE LITTLE QUAINT
STORES, BEAUTIFUL LITTLE STORES
AND THEN COME THIS WAY.
YOU CAN SEE JUST THE MEDIA, AND
PEOPLE HAVE TAKEN THIS SQUARE
OVER.
WHEN I TALK TO PEOPLE HERE, THEY
SAY, THERE'S NEVER THIS MANY
PEOPLE, THERE ARE NEVER THIS
MANY PEOPLE WHO COME TO THIS
TOWN ON A SATURDAY AND SUNDAY TO
SEE HOW INTIMATE AND HOW
BEAUTIFUL THIS LITTLE TOWN IS,
LOOK.
A CREEK THAT RUNS RIGHT THROUGH
IT.
THE PEOPLE OF THIS SMALL TOWN
PROBABLY NEVER DREEP DREAMED TH
THEIR TOWN WOULD BE THE FOCUS OF
SUCH PANG AND SORROW.
THIS IS THE NEWTOWN UNITED
METHODIST CHURCH.
THIS WHERE A LOT OF MEDIA CAMP
OUT.
THEY GIVE PRESCHOOL CLASSES,
AGES TWO TO SIX.
THERE'S THE CHURCH BEHIND ME.
IT'S BEEN OPENED NOW FOR 24
HOURS.
IT WILL BE OPEN FOR 24 FOURS FOR
AS LONG AS THEY NEED IT SOME OF
THE MEMBERS OF THE CHURCH DIED
AND ANYONE WHO WANTS TO COME BY
AND PAY THEIR RESPECTS TO THE
PEOPLE WHO DIED.
ANYONE WHO NEEDS HELP FROM THIS
CHURCH, THEY CAN COME HERE AND
GET IT.
FOR MORE INFORMATION ON HOW YOU
CAN HELP THOSE AFFECTED BY THE
SHOOTING, YOU CAN GO TO
CNN.COM/IMPACT.
THAT'S A LIVE MAKESHIFT MEMBER
YAT, A VIGIL FOR THE PEOPLE WHO
LOST THEIR LIVES.
THIS ONE IS NOT FAR FROM WHERE I
AM.
YOU SEE THE POLICE CAR RIGHT
THERE ON THE HILL.
THAT'S THE SCHOOL.
THAT'S THE ROAD THAT LEADS TO
THE SCHOOL HERE.
AND THERE ARE 26 CANDLES FOR
EVERY PERSON WHO DIED INSIDE OF
THAT SCHOOL.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT A SQUARE IT
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, LIVE
PICTURES RIGHT NOW.
TRYING TO MAKE SENSE OF A
MASSACRE, WE'RE GOING TO LOOK AT
THE QUIET, AFFLUENT NEIGHBORHOOD
OF SANDY LOOK AND TALK WITH
PEOPLE WHO KNEW THE YOUNG MAN
WHO IS ACCUSED OF DOING ALL
THIS.
[ Woman ]
♪ WHAT I WANT THIS SEASON
♪ IF YOU'D LIKE
TO TRY AND GUESS ♪
♪ IT IS SOMETHING VERY SPECIAL
♪ I WOULD READILY CONFESS
[ dogs barking ]
♪ 'CAUSE ALL I WANT
THIS SEASON ♪
♪ IS SOMETHING FROM YOUR HEART
♪ LA DA DA, LA DA DA
[ Male Announcer ] THINKING
OF OTHERS THIS HOLIDAY SEASON,
TRAVELERS.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE WAY IT MOVES.
THE WAY IT CLEANS.
EVERYTHING ABOUT
THE ORAL-B POWER BRUSH
IS SIMPLY REVOLUTIONARY.
ORAL-B POWER BRUSHES OSCILLATE,
ROTATE
AND EVEN PULSATE
TO GENTLY LOOSEN AND BREAK UP
THAT STICKY PLAQUE
WITH MORE BRUSH MOVEMENTS
THAN MANUAL BRUSHES
AND EVEN
UP TO 50% MORE
THAN LEADING
SONIC TECHNOLOGY BRUSHES
FOR A SUPERIOR CLEAN.
ORAL-B POWER BRUSHES.
GO TO ORALB.COM
FOR THE LATEST OFFERS.