>>> A REMINDER YOU NEED THAT
ESPECIALLY NOW THERE ARE GOOD
PEOPLE AND ACTS OF KINDNESS
HAPPENING EVERY DAY.
REMEMBER THIS LAST MONTH?
NEW YORK POLICE OFFICER MADE
NEWS BY OFFERING A HOMELESS MAN
HIS SHOES ON A COLD NIGHT.
A TENNESSEE BOY HELPS HIS
BROTHER IN A WHEELCHAIR COMPETE
IN A TRIATHLON.
PEOPLE DOING GOOD.
I'M VICTOR BLACKWELL AT THE
HEADQUARTERS IN ATLANTA.
>>> A SMALL TOWN SMOTHERED IN
GRIEF AND A NATION IN DISBELIEF.
I'M CANDY CROWLEY IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>>> TODAY, THE UNTHINKABLE AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> YOU CAN NEVER BE PREPARED FOR
THIS KIND OF INCIDENT.
>> THE LATEST ON THE
INVESTIGATION WITH CONNECTICUT
GOVERNOR DAN MALLOY, AND THEN
GRIEF AND GUNS.
A CONVERSATION WITH THE COLORADO
GOVERN
GOVERNOR.
PLUS, EXPERTS ON KEEPING SCHOOL
SAFE COPING WITH TRAUMA AND
PROFILING A MASS MURDERER, ALL
ON THIS SPECIAL EDITION OF
"STATE OF THE UNION."
FIRST, THE LATEST ON THE NEWTOWN
MURDERS.
THIS MORNING CONNECTICUT'S CHIEF
MEDICAL EXAMINER WILL PERFORM
AUTOPSIES ON THE GUNMAN AND HIS
MOTHER, WHO WAS KILLED AT HER
HOME.
THE RESULTS WILL BE RELEASED
DURING A NEWS CONFERENCE LATER
TODAY.
THE NAMES OF THE VICTIMS WERE
MADE PUBLIC LAST NIGHT.
12 GIRLS AND 8 BOYS KILLED, ALL
EITHER 6 OR 7 YEARS OLD.
THE SIX ADULTS KILLED AT THE
SCHOOL WERE WOMEN.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER SAYS EVERY
VICTIM HE SAW WAS HIT MORE THAN
ONCE, AND ALL THE WOUNDS HE SAW
WERE INFLICTED BY THE
SEMI-AUTOMATIC RIFLE FOUND AT
THE SCENE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL BE HERE IN
NEWTOWN LATE THIS AFTERNOON TO
MEET WITH THE VICTIMS' FAMILIES
AND SPEAK AT AN EVENING
MEMORIAL.
CNN NATIONAL CORRESPONDENT SUSAN
CANDIOTTI IS OUTSIDE THE HOME
THE GUNMAN AND HIS MOTHER
SHARED.
SUSAN, LET ME BRING YOU IN.
TELL ME, WHAT IS THE LATEST ON
THE INVESTIGATION?
>> Reporter: WE KNOW THAT THE
INVESTIGATORS INCLUDING ATF
AGENTS WILL BE CONTINUING TO
POUND THE STREETS TODAY CHASING
DOWN LEADS THAT THEY HAVE
LOOKING INTO WHAT IS BEING TOLD
TO ME, DESCRIBED TO ME AS THE
ACTIVITIES OF THE SHOOTER.
THEY'RE NOT GIVING A TIME FRAME.
IF THEY'RE TALKING ABOUT ONLY
THE DAYS LEADING UP TO THIS OR
ALL OF THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER'S
ACTIVITIES.
OBVIOUSLY, THEY'RE TRYING TO GET
DOWN TO THE BOTTOM OF WHAT
MOTIVATED HIM TO CARRY OUT THIS
OBVIOUSLY SENSELESS CRIME AND
HOW IT WAS THAT HE GOT HIS HANDS
ON THOSE GUNS THAT CAME FROM HIS
MOTHER'S HOME THAT WERE LEGALLY
PURCHASED BY THE MOTHER
ACCORDING TO AUTHORITIES.
WE ALSO KNOW THEY HAVE COMPLETED
THE TRACES ON THOSE THREE GUNS
WE'VE BEEN TELLING YOU ABOUT,
THE TWO HANDGUNS AS WELL AS THE
SEMI-AUTOMATIC RIFLE CALLED THE
BUSHMASTER.
THE
THEY WERE ALL FOUND IN THE
CLASSROOM WITH THE SHOOTER AND
THEY KNOW WHICH ONE HE USED TO
KILL HIMSELF AND DID NOT REVEAL
THAT.
BACK TO TODAY'S ACTIVITIESES
THEY HAVE A LOT OF TERRITORY TO
COVER.
I'M TOLD THERE ARE AT LEAST 400
GUN DEALERS IN THIS FOUR-COUNTY
AREA AS WELL AS 30 GUN RANGES
AND THEY PLAN TO MAKE CONTACT
WITH EACH AND EVERY ONE OF THEM
AND THERE ARE ONLY 30 AGENTS
WORKING AT TRYING TO ACCOMPLISH
THAT VERY DIFFICULT TASK.
SO CANDY, THEY HAVE A LOT OF
WORK TO DO TO GET DOWN TO THE
BOTTOM OF WHAT STARTED THIS,
WHERE THOSE GUNS CAME FROM, HOW
HE GOT HIS HANDS ON THEM,
WHETHER HE TRAINED ON THOSE
WEAPONS.
THOSE ARE THE KINDS OF QUESTIONS
THEY'RE ASKING.
WIRE TRYI
WE'RE TRYING TO FIND OUT IF HE
LEFT BEGINNING BEHIND WRITTEN
DOWN.
SO FAR I'VE HEARD NOTHING ABOUT
THAT.
BACK TO YOU, CANDY.
>> THANKS.
FOLLOWING THE INVESTIGATION OF
THIS HORRIFIC CRIME FOR US AT
CNN, I SPOKE A SHORT WHILE AGO
WITH CONNECTICUT'S GOVERNOR
ABOUT THE INVESTIGATION.
GOVERNOR, THANK YOU FOR JOINING
US HERE.
LET ME JUST FIRST ASK YOU ABOUT
THE STATE OF THE INVESTIGATION.
WHAT DO WE NOW KNOW AND WHERE
ARE WE IN THE INVESTIGATION?
>> FIRST AND FOREMOST, THAT'S
THE STATE POLICE HANDLING THAT
INVESTIGATION.
I THINK WE KNOW EVERYTHING THAT
IS MOST IMPORTANT.
WE KNOW THAT THERE WAS A SINGLE
SHOOTER.
THAT THAT SHOOTER IS DEAD.
WE KNOW THAT HE WAS A TROUBLED
INDIVIDUAL AND THAT HE WENT TO
THE SCHOOL WITH A NUMBER OF
WEAPONS, WHICH HE USED ON HIS
VICTIMS AND ULTIMATELY USED ON
HIMSELF.
YOU KNOW, SOME OF THIS OTHER
STUFF WILL PLAY OUT OVER A
PERIOD OF TIME.
I'M SURE WE'LL COME TO KNOW MORE
P HIM, HIS PROBLEMS AND HIS
FAMILY.
YOU KNOW, THESE THINGS MOVE ON.
THIS INVESTIGATION WILL TELL US
THOSE THINGS, BUT, YOU KNOW, I
DON'T HAVE A WHOLE LOT MORE THAN
THAT.
>> SO TELL ME, LET ME GO BACK TO
A COUPLE THINGS YOU JUST SAID.
THE FIRST IS THE WEAPONRY.
SO FAR AS YOU KNOW, WERE THESE
WEAPONS LEGALLY OBTAINED BY THE
MOTHER, WHICH WE'RE LED TO
BELIEVE THEY WERE HER WEAPONS?
>> THE MOTHER PURCHASED THEM.
THEY HAVE THE PATINA OF LEGAL
PURCHASES.
THERE'S ALWAYS A QUESTION WAS
SHE PURCHASING THEM FOR HERSELF,
WHICH IN THAT CASE IT WAS LEGAL.
IF SHE WAS PURCHASING THEM FOR
ANOTHER INDIVIDUAL, HER SON,
THEN THERE'S A QUESTION ABOUT
THAT PURCHASE.
>> DO WE KNOW ANYTHING THAT
INDICATES THAT?
>> THE OTHER THING IS THIS
ASSAULT WEAPON.
CONNECTICUT HAS A PRETTY AGGR  S
AGGRESSIVE LAW PROBABLY OF THE
50 STATES, WE'RE RANKED FOURTH
MOST AGGRESSIVE IN TRYING TO
LIMIT ACCESS TO THESE KINDS OF
WEAPONS.
WHAT HAPPENS IN THE ABSENCE OF A
BRADY BILL, IN THE ABSENCE OF
FEDERAL LEGISLATION, PEOPLE USE
DESCRIPTIVE TERMS TO TRY TO GET
AROUND THE LIMITATIONS THAT ARE
BUILT INTO OUR STATUTES HERE IN
CONNECTICUT OR MIGHT OTHERWISE
NOT HAPPEN IF WE HAD FEDERAL
LEGISLATION ON THIS ISSUE.
THESE ARE ASSAULT WEAPONS.
YOU DON'T HUNT DEER WITH THESE
THINGS.
I THINK THAT'S THE QUESTION THAT
A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE GOING TO
HAVE TO RESOLVE THEIR OWN MINDS.
WHERE SHOULD THIS LINE GET
DRAWN?
>> SO AS I UNDERSTAND WHAT
YOU'RE SAYING, THERE WAS A SEMI
ASSAULT WEAPON BUT NOT
NECESSARILY ONE BANNED BY
CONNECTICUT, WHICH HAS A STATE
LAW BANNING CERTAIN KINDS OF
ASSAULT WEAPONS?
>> THAT BEGS THE QUESTION, WAS
THIS A WEAPON THAT SHOULD HAVE
BEEN BANNED, AND BECAUSE OF HOW
THE MANUFACTURER DECIDED TO
DESCRIBE IT GOT AROUND THAT LAW?
>> LET ME GO BACK TO A COUPLE
THINGS YOU SAID.
THE FIRST IS, IS THERE ANYTHING
THAT LEADS YOU TO BELIEVE SHE
MIGHT HAVE PURCHASED THEM FOR
HER SON, OR IS THAT JUST HERE
ARE THE POSSIBILITIES?
>> HERE ARE THE POSSIBILITIES.
THEY'RE LIVING TOGETHER.
THEY'RE IN THE HOME.
HE ENDS UP WITH THE GUNS, SO
THERE MAY BE AN EXPLANATION.
>> THEY'RE LOOKING INTO THAT.
THE OTHER ISSUE DESCRIBED HIS AS
TROUBLED, WHICH WE KNOW FROM
WHAT HE DID.
IS THERE OTHER EVIDENCE AS
THEY'VE GONE IN ABOUT TROUBLED
HOW?
>> YOU KNOW, CLEARLY, HE WAS
TROUBLED.
YOU HAVE TO BE DERANGED TO CARRY
OUT THIS KIND OF CRIME.
YOU KNOW, I'M NOT IN A POSITION
THAT I SHOULD BE TALKING ABOUT
SOMEONE ELSE'S FAMILY.
THAT INFORMATION WILL COME OUT
IN DUE COURSE, BUT THIS WAS
CLEARLY A TROUBLED PERSON.
>> IS THERE EVIDENCE THAT HE WAS
MENTALLY DISABLED IN SOME WAY?
>> THERE'S EVIDENCE THAT HE WAS
MENTALLY DISABLED BY THE ACTS
THAT HE COMMITTED.
ONE DOESN'T SHOOT THEIR
MOTHER --
>> NOTHING BEHIND THAT THAT YOU
FIND IN THE INVESTIGATION THUS
FAR?
>> THERE ARE -- AS HAS BEEN
ATTESTED TO ALREADY BY FAMILY
MEMBERS AND OTHERS IN THE
NEWSPAPERS, THIS WAS A TROUBLED
INDIVIDUAL.
>> OKAY.
AS FAR AS THE GUNS ARE
CONCERNED, DO THEY COME OUT OF
THE HOME?
IS THAT WHERE THEY -- WERE THEY
SECURED IN THE HOME?
>> YES, THAT'S OUR BELIEF.
>> LET ME MOVE YOU ON TO YOUR
ROLE NOW.
THERE ALWAYS COMES THIS POINT
WHERE THE INVESTIGATION IS
ONGOING.
THIS INCREDIBLE GRIEF THESE
FAMILIES MUST BE AND ARE
SUFFERING IS GOING ON.
WHAT DO YOU DO NOW?
>> YOU KNOW, CANDY, I WAS WITH
THE VAST MAJORITY OF THE
FAMILIES FRIDAY MORNING, AND
ULTIMATELY I HAD TO BREAK IT TO
ALL OF THE FOLKS WHO WERE
ASSEMBLED AT THE FIREHOUSE THAT
THEIR CHILDREN OR LOVED ONE IN
THE CASE OF THE ADULTS WERE NOT
COMING HOME.
AND THAT'S AN EXERCISE THAT I
WILL LIVE WITH FOR THE REST OF
MY LIFE.
IT'S NOT SOMETHING YOU'RE
PREPARED FOR, AND YOU GO ON.
BUT, YOU KNOW, LISTEN, I'M THE
GOVERNOR OF THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT.
WE HAVE A JOB TO DO.
WE HAVE TO PICTURE PEOPLE AND
HELP PEOPLE RECOVER AND MOVE ON
AND GET CHILDREN BACK TO SCHOOL
AS QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE IN THE
BROADER SYSTEM AND HOPEFULLY
THESE CHILDREN AT THIS SCHOOL
BACK TO SCHOOL -- A SCHOOL AS
QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE.
>> TO MAKE SURE I UNDERSTOOD YOU
CORRECTLY.
YOU'RE THE ONE THAT INITIALLY
HAD TO TELL THE FAMILIES
GATHERED IN THAT ROOM WHAT MANY
FEARED OR SINCE SOME OF THEM
MIGHT HAVE ALREADY KNOWN AT A
GUT LEVEL, YOU WERE THE ONE THAT
FINALIZED IT FOR THEM?
>> YES.
>> TELL ME P ABOUT THAT MOMENT.
>> IT'S A VERY DIFFICULT THING
TO DO.
THESE PARENTS HAD BEEN GATHERED
FOR A NUMBER OF HOURS CLINGING
TO HOPE.
NEWS REPORTS WERE SWIRLING
AROUND THEM OUTSIDE THE
BUILDING.
SOMEONE HAD TO DECIDE HOW TO
HANDLE THAT SITUATION.
ULTIMATELY IT FELL UPON ME TO DO
THAT.
YOU KNOW, YOU CAN NEVER BE
PREPARED FOR THAT, TO TELL 18 OR
20 FOLKS OR ACTUALLY FAMILIES
THAT THEIR LOVED ONE WOULD NOT
BE RETURNING TO THEM THAT DAY OR
IN THE FUTURE IT IS A TOUGH
ASSIGNMENT.
>> LET ME ASK YOU ABOUT THE
SCHOOL ITSELF.
WE KNOW THAT THERE WAS A BUZZ-IN
SYSTEM.
AS YOU LOOK AT THAT AS A
GOVERNOR, KNOWING THE TIMES WE
LIVE IN, THE SORTS OF THINGS
THAT HAPPEN, AS FAR AS I KNOW,
CORRECT ME IF I'M WRONG, WE'VE
YET TO TURN UP A HISTORY OF
MENTAL HEALTH PROBLEMS IN TERMS
OF GOING TO A PSYCHIATRIST OR
SHOWING ANY SIGNS OF, YOU KNOW,
I'M GOING TO GO DO A HORRIBLE
THING.
WE'VE HAD A COUPLE OF THESE
WHERE THERE'S NO KIND OF HISTORY
TO IT.
SO WE KNOW THAT IF SOMEONE IS
DETERMINED AND IT'S A FIRST-TIME
THING THAT THESE KINDS OF THINGS
CAN UP HAPPEN.
DO YOU LOOK AT SCHOOLS IN
CONNECTICUT NOW AND THINK, WE
HAVE TO DO BETTER IN SECURITY,
OR WE NEED A SECURITY PERSONNEL
AT THESE SCHOOLS?
WHERE DO THE TIMES TAKE US IN
TERMS OF PROTECTING WHAT WE
ALWAYS ASSUMED WERE SACRED
GROUND, WHICH IS SCHOOLS?
>> WHAT WE KNOW IS HE SHOT HIS
WAY INTO THE BUILDING, SO HE
PENETRATED THE BUILDING.
HE WASN'T BUZZED IN.
HE PENETRATED THE BUILDING BY
LITERALLY SHOOTING AN ENTRANCE
INTO THE BUILDING.
THAT'S WHAT AN ASSAULT WEAPON
CAN DO FOR YOU.
YOU KNOW, WE ARE UNFORTUNATELY A
VIOLENT SOCIETY.
32,000-PLUS DEATHS AS A RESULT
OF GUNS BEING USED, 18,000 OF
THOSE WERE SELF-INFLICTED.
THIS IS A VIOLENT WORLD.
WE ARE A PARTICULARLY VIOLENT
COUNTRY WITHIN THAT WORLD, AND
IF SOMEONE WANTS TO DO AN ACT
LIKE THIS, THEY'RE GOING TO FIND
A WAY TO DO IT IF IT'S NOT IN A
BUILDING, IT COULD BE OUTSIDE A
BUILDING.
>> SURE.
THEN DO YOU LOOK AT SECURITY IN
THAT BUILDING AND SAY, THEN WE
HAVE TO HAVE WHATEVER IT COSTS,
SECURITY GUARDS OR SOMETHING, AT
THE DOORS OF SCHOOLS?
>> I READ A QUOTE THE OTHER DAY.
SCHOOLS ARE NOT VAULTS.
THEY'RE NOT BANKS.
PEOPLE HAVE TO COME AND GO.
YOU BUILD THE BEST SYSTEM THAT
YOU CAN UNDERSTANDING WHAT THE
CHALLENGES ARE.
SOME BUILDINGS BECAUSE OF THE
SIZE OF THE STUDENT BODY ARE
EVEN MORE DIFFICULT TO LOCKDOWN.
ALL OF THAT WILL BE TAKEN A LOOK
AT, JUST AS WE DID IN THE
WAKEFUL COLUMBINE.
I'VE BEEN IN PUBLIC SERVICE FOR
A LONG TIME.
I WAS A MAYOR THROUGH THE
AATTACK ON THE WORLD TRADE
CENTER IN A NEARBY CITY WHERE WE
LOST A NUMBER OF OUR CITIZENS
AND HAVE BEEN IN OFFICE THROUGH
A NUMBER OF THESE TYPES OF
EVENTS.
YOU ATTEMPT TO LEARN EVERY
LESSON YOU CAN FROM EACH ONE OF
THESE, AND IT'S A LITTLE EARLY
TO SAY WHAT WE CAN TAKE AWAY
FROM THIS.
THIS IS A LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT
IN THE SENSE THAT TO THE BEST OF
MY KNOWLEDGE IN SCHOOL SHOOTINGS
WE HAVEN'T HAD PEOPLE SHOOT
THEIR WAY INTO A BUILDING.
>> RIGHT.
GOVERNOR, LET ME ASK YOU JUST
EXTRAPOLATING FOR WHAT YOU'RE
SAYING, YOU WANT STRICTER
FEDERAL GUN LAWS BECAUSE NO
MATTER HOW STRICT YOUR STATE LAW
IS, YOU FEEL YOU NEED AN OVERLAY
OF A FEDERAL LAW, IS THAT RIGHT?
>> WHEN WE TALK ABOUT THE
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN THAT WAS IN
PLACE IN THE UNITED STATES, TO
HAVE ALLOWED THAT TO GO AWAY OR
DISSIPATE, IT'S THE STATE'S
ABILITY TO ENFORCE THAT BECAUSE
GUNS MOVE ACROSS STATE LINES.
IN FACT, A LOT OF GUNS USED IN
CRIMES IN CONNECTICUT WERE
PURCHASED AT -- WE KNOW BECAUSE
WE CAN TRACK THEM.
THEY WERE PURCHASED AT GUN SHOWS
IN OTHER STATES PARTICULARLY
DOWN IN THE SOUTHERN PORTION OF
THE UNITED STATES.
THEY WORK UP COAST AND GET HERE.
THAT WAS NOT THE CASE IN THIS
SITUATION.
THE BRADY BILL WAS A PIECE OF
LEGISLATION THAT MADE A LOT OF
SENSE AND STILL DOES, AND ONE
CAN ONLY HOPE THAT WE'LL FIND A
WAY TO LIMIT THESE WEAPONS THAT
REALLY ONLY HAVE ONE PURPOSE.
>> GOVERNOR, THANK YOU FOR YOUR
TIME THIS MORNING.
>> THANK YOU.
WITH WE RETURN, WILL THE GUN
DEBATE LEAD ANYWHERE THIS TIME?
I'LL TALK TO THE GOVERNOR OF
COLORADO.
TAKE TYLENOL OR TAKE ALEVE,
THE #1 RECOMMENDED PAIN
RELIEVER BY ORTHOPEDIC DOCTORS.
JUST TWO ALEVE
CAN KEEP PAIN AWAY ALL DAY.
BACK TO THE NEWS.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN DIARRHEA HITS,
KAOPECTATE STOPS IT FAST.
POWERFUL LIQUID RELIEF
SPEEDS TO THE SOURCE.
FAST.
[ Male Announcer ]
STOP THE UH-OH FAST
WITH KAOPECTATE.
>>> IT'S NOT JUST A FEELING BUT
A FACT.
IT HAS GOTTEN WORSE.
FIVE OF THE 12 DEADLIEST MASS
SHOOTINGS IN U.S. HISTORY HAVE
HAPPENED IN THE LAST FOUR YEARS.
>> AS A NATION WE HAVE ENDURED
FAR TOO MANY OF THESE TRAGEDIES
IN THE LAST FEW YEARS.
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
A SHOPPING MALL IN OREGON, A
HOUSE OF WORSHIP IN WISCONSIN, A
MOVIE THEATER IN COLORADO,
COUNTLESS STREET CORNERS IN
PLACES LIKE CHICAGO AND
PHILADELPHIA.
ANY OF THESE NEIGHBORHOODS COULD
BE OUR OWN.
WE HAVE TO COME TOGETHER, AND
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO TAKE
MEANINGFUL ACTION TO PREVENT
MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS FROM
HAPPENING REGARDLESS OF
POLITICS.
>> IN THAT AURORA THEATER LAST
JULY A GUNMAN WIELDING A
SEMI-AUTOMATIC RIFLE WITH A
100-BARREL MAGAZINE, A SHOTGUN
AND PISTOL WENT ON A RAMPAGE
KILLING 12 AND WOUNDING 58.
SHORTLY AFTERWARDS COLORADO'S
GOVERNOR SAID STRICTER GUN LAWS
WOULD NOT HAVE HELPED.
>> IF THERE WERE NO ASSAULT
WEAPONS AVAILABLE, IF THERE WERE
NO THIS OR THAT, THIS GUY IS
GOING TO FIND SOMETHING AND KNOW
HOW TO CREATE A BOMB.
>> HE SEEMED DIFFERENT IN AN
INTERVIEW LAST WEDNESDAY, TWO
FULL DAYS BEFORE THE EVENTS HERE
IN CONNECTICUT.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT WHAT HAPPENED
IN AURORA, THE GOVERNOR SAID, A
GREAT DEAL OF THAT DAMAGE WAS
FROM THE LARGE MAGAZINE ON THE
AR-15 RIFLE.
I THINK WE NEED TO HAVE THAT
DISCUSSION AND SAY, WHERE IS
THIS APPROPRIATE?
JOINING ANY NOW IS THE GOVERNOR
OF COLORADO, JOHN HICKENLOOPER.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US TODAY.
I THINK THAT THINGS ARE SO FRESH
HERE IN CONNECTICUT, BUT YOU
HAVE BEEN DEALING FOR SEVERAL
MONTHS WITH THE AFTERMATH OF
WHAT HAPPENED IN AURORA.
I WONDER IF YOU HAVE -- IF I AM
MISINTERPRETING YOU OR
INTERPRETING YOU CORRECTLY THAT
MAYBE YOU HAVE SOME SLIGHT
EVOLUTION ON WHAT OUGHT TO BE
DONE IN TERMS OF LAWS INVOLVING
GUNS OR AMMUNITIONS.
>> FIRST, LET ME JUST SAY THAT,
THE HEART OF EVERY PERSON IN
COLORADO GOES OUT TO EVERY
PERSON IN CONNECTICUT.
WATCHING GOVERNOR MALLOY
NAVIGATE, AND I THINK DONE A
REMARKABLE JOB, BUT WE WOULD --
YOU KNOW, OUR HEARTS ARE
BREAKING THERE FOR THEM.
WE KNOW EXACTLY HOW THEY FEEL.
WE'VE BEEN COLLECTING AND EVEN
AS THEY STRUGGLE TO PROCESS THIS
WE'VE HAD THAT DISTANCE SINCE
THE SHOOTING IN AURORA.
I'VE REALLY TRIED TO LOOK AT
WHAT ARE THE THINGS THAT COULD
MAKE A DIFFERENCE, AND HOW
SHOULD WE BEGIN THIS
CONVERSATION?
THINGS LIKE HIGH CAPACITY
MAGAZIN
MAGAZINES CERTAINLY HAVE -- THAT
COMES UP AGAIN AND AGAIN AND
AGAIN.
THE EXPANDING BACKGROUND CHECKS
TO MAKE SURE THAT GUNS DON'T END
UP IN THE WRONG PEOPLE'S HANDS.
WE HAD PLANNED A PRESS
CONFERENCE FOR TUESDAY WHERE WE
HAVE A WHOLE LIST OF EFFORTS,
ALMOST $20 MILLION IN NEW
PROGRAMS AROUND TRYING TO PUT
MORE SUPPORT FOR PEOPLE WITH
MENTAL ILLNESS, TO MAKE SURE WE
HAVE A 24-HOUR HOT LINE TT
SOMEONE CAN CALL IN IF THEY
THINK SOMEONE APPEARS UNSTABLE,
A DANGER TO THEMSELVES AND
OTHERS.
MAKE SURE WE EXPAND CAPACITY IN
NEIGHBORHOODS AND COMMUNITIES
ACROSS THE STATE.
THAT WE HAVE A PLACE TO
STABILIZE PEOPLE IF THEY APPEAR
LIKE THEY'RE A THREAT TO
THEMSELVES OR TO OTHERS.
I MEAN, THAT WHOLE PROGRAM WAS
ALL IN PLACE, AND THAT'S
SOMETHING WE CAN DO IMMEDIATELY
WITHOUT GETTING INTO SOME OF THE
BATTLES OF GUN LEGALIZATION OR
GUN -- RESTRICTING ACCESS TO
GUNS IN SOME WAY.
THAT DISCUSSION OF GUN SAFETY IS
GOING TO CONTINUE.
>> I THINK ALSO, GOVERNOR, THAT
WE TALKED ABOUT THE FACT THAT
SOMEONE THAT ISN'T IN A MENTAL
HEALTH SYSTEM AND A NUMBER OF
FOLKS -- YOURS WAS THE EXCEPTION
IN THE BEGINNING.
A NUMBER OF THE PEOPLE, I THINK,
PARTICULARLY IN TUCSON, HAD NOT
SOUGHT OUT ANY KIND OF MENTAL
HEALTH HELP.
SO THEY WOULDN'T HAVE BEEN
CAUGHT UP IN A SYSTEM THAT
NECESSARILY WOULD HAVE LOOKED AT
THAT IN THE PURCHASE OF GUNS.
WE ALSO KNOW THAT GUNS ARE
READILY AVAILABLE EVEN IF YOU
DON'T PURCHASE THEM LEGALLY.
I THINK WE TALKED THAT TIME
ABOUT THE CULTURE OF GUNS AND
KIND OF THE CULTURE THAT WE LIVE
IN NOW AND THAT THERE'S VERY
LITTLE YOU CAN DO TO STOP A
DETERMINED PERSON.
DO YOU STILL FEEL THAT WAY?
>> WELL, UNFORTUNATELY, I THINK
THAT'S TRUE.
I MEAN, YOU CAN'T REALLY ARGUE
THOSE FACTS.
WHAT YOU CAN DO IS EXPAND THE
CAPACITY, YOUR FRAMEWORK WITHIN
A STATE OR WITHIN THE COUNTRY TO
HAVE MORE PEOPLE PAYING
ATTENTION AND TRYING TO DETECT
FOLKS THAT ARE UNSTABLE ON THE
VERGE OF REAL TROUBLE, TRYING TO
CATCH THEM AT A SOONER LEVEL.
CERTAINLY THE CULTURE OF
VIOLENCE -- LOOK AT THE LEVEL OF
VIOLENCE IN OUR MEDIA, VIDEO
GAMES, THE DEPICTION OF THESE
ASSAULT WEAPONS AGAIN AND AGAIN,
THERE MIGHT WELL BE SOME DIRECT
CONNECTION BETWEEN PEOPLE WHO
HAVE MENTAL INSTABILITY, AND
WHEN THEY GO OVER THE EDGE THEY
TRANS THEMSELVES AND BECOME
PARTS OF THE VIDEO GAMES AND
PERHAPS THAT'S WHY ALL THESE
ASSAULT WEAPONS ARE USED.
>> GOVERNOR, LET ME ASK YOU.
HAVE YOU -- FIRST OF ALL, I
UNDERSTOOD THAT YOU HAVE SPOKEN
OR COMMUNICATED WITH THE
GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT.
WHAT DOES THIS TOWN, THIS STATE,
IF YOU WILL, GO THROUGH NOW?
YOUR INCIDENT HAPPENED IN JULY.
IT WAS HORRIFIC.
YOU'VE SORT OF SEEN THE
EVOLUTION OF THE MONTHS.
WHAT'S NEXT, AND WHAT KIND OF
ADVICE DO YOU HAVE FOR THE
CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR?
>> WELL, I'M NOT SURE HE NEEDS
ADVICE FROM ME.
WHAT I REMEMBER --
>> YOU'VE BEEN THERE.
>> YEAH, I KNOW.
I REMEMBER THE -- HOW SURREAL IT
WAS.
IT SEEMED LIKE THIS COULDN'T BE
HAPPENING.
AS YOU TALKED TO ONE FAMILY
AFTER ANOTHER, THEY'RE ALL
DEALING WITH SOMETHING BEYOND
ANYTHING THEY COULD HAVE
IMAGINED.
YOU KNOW, IT'S THE WORST THING
THEY WILL SEE IN THEIR LIVES,
ONE PERSON AFTER ANOTHER AFTER
ANOTHER.
IT DOES -- I THINK GOVERNOR
MALLOY IS, AGAIN, THE RIGHT
PERSON AT THE RIGHT TIME FOR
CONNECTICUT.
YOU CAN ALREADY SEE HE HAS THAT
COURAGE, BECAUSE HE HAS TO GO
OUT TO FAMILIES AGAIN AND AGAIN
AND TRY TO BE THERE WITH THEM
AND HELP THEM GET THROUGH THIS
AND PROCESS IT.
IT IS.
IT'S JUST UNSPEAKABLY HARD.
YOU CAN'T -- THERE AREN'T WORDS.
DON'T KNOW HOW TO PUT IT IN
WORDS.
>> YOU KNOW, AS A GOVERNOR THESE
ARE CONSTITUENTS BUT NOT
NECESSARILY FAMILIES YOU KNEW,
AND YET, YOU'RE KIND OF PLAYING
THIS KEY ROLE.
SO IN THE MONTHS SINCE THE AA  R
AURORA THEATER SHOOTING, DOES
YOUR OFFICE CONTINUE TO SPEAK
AND TRY TO HELP THOSE FAMILIES
AND WHAT ARE THOSE NEEDS IN
THERE?
>> WELL, IN VARYING DEGREES
CERTAINLY THERE WAS A FUND SET
UP TO TRY AND PROVIDE SUPPORT
AND RESOURCES TO THE FAMILIES OF
THE VICTIMS AND TO THE WOUNDED
VICTIMS.
THAT PROCESS WAS CHALLENGING
ITSELF.
MONEY CAN'T REPLACE ESPECIALLY
WITH YOUNG PEOPLE.
IT'S SO INSUFFICIENT, AND YET,
IT BECOMES THIS SYMBOL.
WE WERE CHALLENGED AT EVERY STEP
ALONG THAT WAY.
REALLY, A LOT OF THE FAMILIES
JUST NEED SOMEONE THEY CAN TALK
TO, THAT THEY CAN RELATE TO IN
THOSE DAYS IMMEDIATELY AFTER THE
TRAGEDY, IN A NUMBER OF CASES I
FELT LIKE I WAS PART OF THE
FAMILY.
YOU'RE BROUGHT IN IN A VERY
INTIMATE LEVEL, AND AGAIN HAVING
THESE DISCUSSIONS THAT PEOPLE
ARE REVEALING THEMSELVES AND
THEIR RESILIENCE.
THEIR ABILITY TO TAKE THIS AWFUL
THING AND FIND A WAY TO MAKE
THEIR LIFE HE BETTER.
YOU KNOW, SOME OF THE MOST
CHALLENGING TIMES THAT I'VE EVER
BEEN THROUGH.
>> HAVE YOU FOUND, GOVERNOR, AS
A FINAL QUESTION, THAT THOSE
FAMILIES OR THE PEOPLE IN AURORA
OR THE PEOPLE OF COLORADO
PRESSURE YOU NOW MORE FOR SOME
SORT OF GUN CONTROL?
DO YOU THINK THE TIME HAS COME
FOR THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT TO
ALTHOUAT
LEAST HAVE THAT CONVERSATION?
DO YOU THINK THERE'S SOMETHING
TO BE DONE ON THE FEDERAL LEVEL
IN TERMS OF A LAW BANNING
HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINES OR,
AGAIN, REINSTITUTING THE BAN ON
ASSAULT WEAPONS?
DO YOU THINK IT'S TIME FOR THAT,
OR AT LEAST A CONVERSATION ABOUT
THAT?
>> WELL, I THINK THE ACCESS TO
GUNS IS GOING TO GET DISCUSSED
AND CERTAINLY I THINK
HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINES AS
PEOPLE ARE DISCUSSING THIS.
WE ARE -- I MEAN, OUR COUNTRY IS
BASED ON THAT SECOND AMENDMENT.
IT'S BEEN SHOWN REPEATEDLY IT
DOES PROTECT PEOPLE'S RIGHTS TO
BEAR ARMS, TO HAVE GUNS.
YOU KNOW, MY GRANDFATHER TAUGHT
ME HOW TO SHOOT AND CLEAN A 12
GAUGE SHOTGUN AND SHOWED ME HOW
TO HUNT, AND I'VE SHOWN MY SON.
THAT TRADITION IS VERY POWERFUL
THROUGHOUT THIS COUNTRY.
>> SURE.
>> YOU KNOW, THE DISCUSSIONS
AROUND ASSAULT WEAPONS AND
HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINES AND
WHO -- YOU KNOW, WHAT TYPE OF --
SHOULD THERE BE A WAIT?
ONE OF THE THINGS WE'RE DOING IN
COLORADO IS EXPANDING THE TIME
IF SOMEONE HAS HAD A MENTAL
ILLNESS HOLD, EXPAND THE TIME
THEY HAVE TO WAIT BEFORE THEY
CAN GET ACCESS TO A FIREARM.
THOSE KINDS OF THINGS, I THINK
THOSE DISCUSSIONS ARE GOING TO
HAPPEN, I HE MEAN, IN REAL TIME
OVER THE NEXT COUPLE MONTHS.
>> GOVERNOR HICKENLOOPER, WE
THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME THIS
MORNING.
>> THANK YOU.
>> SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY HAD
SECURITY MEASURES, BUT THEY WERE
NOT ENOUGH TO STOP A KILLER.
I'LL TALK WITH A MAN THAT
STUDIES SCHOOL VIOLENCE AND ASK
HIM IF THERE'S ANYTHING WE CAN
DO TO FIND AND STOP THE NEXT
MADMAN.
COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
CALL OR CLICK TODAY.
TO THE BEST VACATION
SP(ALL) THE GULF!
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHICH OF
OUR GREAT STATES FOLKS VISIT.
MISSISSIPPI,
ALABAMA,
LOUISIANA
OR FLORIDA,
THEY'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
SHAUL, YOUR ALABAMA
HOSPITALITY IS INCREDIBLE.
THANKS, KAREN.
LOVE YOUR MISSISSIPPI OUTDOORS.
I VOTE FOR YOUR
FLORIDA BEACHES, DAWN.
BILL, THIS LOUISIANA
SEAFOOD IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR ON THE GULF,
WE'VE DECIDED TO PUT
ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
NOW IS THE PERFECT TIME TO
VISIT ANYONE OF OUR STATES.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE, GO FISHING
OR JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
WE'VE GOT COASTLINE TO EXPLORE
AND WILDLIFE TO PHOTOGRAPH.
AND THERE'S WORLD CLASS DINING
WITH OUR WORLD FAMOUS SEAFOOD.
SO FOR A GREAT VACATION
THIS YEAR, COME TO THE GULF.
ITS ALL FABULOUS BUT
I GIVE FLORIDA THE EDGE.
RIGHT AFTER MISSISSIPPI.
YOU MEAN ALABAMA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
THIS INVITATION IS
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP
AND ALL OF US WHO
CALL THE GULF HOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN DIARRHEA HITS,
KAOPECTATE STOPS IT FAST.
POWERFUL LIQUID RELIEF
SPEEDS TO THE SOURCE.
FAST.
[ Male Announcer ]
STOP THE UH-OH FAST
WITH KAOPECTATE.
>>> WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT
THE 20-YEAR-OLD GUNMAN IN THE
NEWTOWN SCHOOL SHOOTINGS.
COURT DOCUMENTS SHOW ADAM
LANZA'S PARENTS DIVORCED IN
2009, HIS FATHER REMARRIED.
HE LIVED WITH HIS MOTHER AND HAS
NO KNOWN CRIMINAL RECORDS OF THE
ONE OF THE HIS AUNTS SAID LANZA
HAD ISSUES WITH LEARNING AND
DESCRIBED HIS AS, QUOTE,
DEFINITELY THE CAL LENG OF THE
FAMILY.
THEY SAY SHE BATTLED WITH THE
SCHOOL BOARD AND ENDED UP HAVING
HER SON HOME SCHOOLED.
JOINING ME NOW WITH INSIGHT ON
PROFILING A KILLER IS FORENSIC
SKA
SKAUL YIS MA HANLDY.
IT'S SO FAR OUT OF THE REALM OF
MAINSTREAM THINKING YOU DON'T
KNOW THE QUESTIONS TO ASK.
WHAT DRIVES THE KIND OF -- I'M
ASSUMING IT'S ANGER THAT CAUSES
SOMEONE WITH NO CRIMINAL RECORD
TO JUST POP LIKE THIS AND DO
SOMETHING SO HORRIFIC?
>> WELL, TYPICALLY THERE IS A
LOT OF ANGER WITH A PERSON LIKE
THIS.
ON TOP OF IT, AN OBSESSION WITH
POWER OBTAINED THROUGH VIOLENCE.
THE IDEA THAT ONE CAN HAVE
OMNIPITENT POWER AND CONTROL AS
AN ANTIDOTE FOR THE
POWERLESSNESS THEY EXPERIENCED
IN LIFE IN OTHER WAYS.
THERE ARE COMMONALTIES IN THE
INDIVIDUALS.
HOPELESSNESS, DESPERATION,
USUALLY SELF-DESTRUCTIVENESS,
AND OFTENTIMES USUALLY, IN FACT,
THERE ARE WARNING SIGNS THAT ARE
THERE TO BE DISCOVERED, THAT CAN
BE REPORTED.
THIS KIND OF LEAKAGE CAN ENABLE
US TO DISRUPT AN UNFOLDING
VIOLENT PATHWAY.
>> NOW, LISTENING TO SOME OF THE
WHAT THE AUNT SAID DESCRIBING
LANZA AS DEFINITELY THE
CHALLENGE OF THE FAMILY, I'M NOT
SURE I KNOW A PARENT WHO CAN'T
SAY THAT ABOUT A PARTICULAR
CHILD.
A CHALLENGE, HOW DO YOU KNOW
WHEN A CHALLENGE TURNS INTO A
DANGER?
WHAT ARE THOSE SIGNS?
>> THE CHALLENGE IS A VERY
GENERAL WORD, BUT WHAT WE'RE
LOOKING FOR ARE PEOPLE THAT ARE
TALKING ABOUT VIOLENCE IN A WAY
THAT SUGGESTS THAT THEY'RE
IDENTIFYING WITH OTHER SHOOTERS,
PEOPLE THAT ARE TALKING MAYBE
ABOUT THEIR OWN DEMISE, PEOPLE
OVERLY INTERESTED IN OTHER
SHOOTINGS THAT HAVE HAPPENED,
MASS SHOOTINGS, AND MAYBE ARE
INVOLVED WITH RELATING TO
FIREARMS WEAPONRY IN A WAY THAT
IS OBVIOUSLY -- IT USUALLY IS
OBVIOUS.
OBVIOUSLY DYSFUNCTIONAL.
SO CHALLENGE IN THESE SITUATIONS
USUALLY DISTINGUISHES ITSELF AND
FAIRLY OBVIOUS TO AN OUTSIDER
LOOKING AT IT.
IT CREATES DISCOMFORT IN THE
SENSE THAT SOMETHING IS REALLY
OFF AND WRONG, AND THOSE KINDS
OF SITUATIONS CAN BE REPORTED TO
LAW ENFORCEMENT, THEY CAN BE
REPORTED IT TO SCHOOL
AUTHORITIES WHO NOW ARE MORE
OFTEN CREATING THREAT ASSESSMENT
TEAMS THAT CAN LOOK AT
CIRCUMSTANCES BEFORE THEY
HAPPEN, INVESTIGATE, ASSESS, AND
DISRUPT THEM.
WE'VE BEEN HAVING GREAT SUCCESS
IN MANY CASES YOU DON'T HEAR
ABOUT WHERE THIS LEAKAGE HAS
BEEN REPORTED BY PEOPLE IN
COMMUNITIES, PARENTS OF KIDS WHO
ARE CONCERNED, CLASSMATES, THE
OPPORTUNITY IS NEARLY ALWAYS
THERE TO DISCOVER AND DISRUPT.
THAT'S THE TAKE-AWAY MESSAGE
HERE.
>> RIGHT.
AS FAR AS WE KNOW, AT LEAST I
DON'T KNOW THAT THIS YOUNG MAN
WAS 20 WAS ACTUALLY IN SCHOOL
AND THAT HE WAS SORT OF
DESCRIBED AS A LOANER A ELONER
ALONE WITH HIS MOTHER.
I CAN SEE HOW OUTSIDERS BEGAN TO
SPOT IT.
SHE'D LIVED WITH THIS CHILD FOR
20 YEARS SO SHE MIGHT HAVE BEEN
UNABLE TO SEE SOMETHING HAD
CHANGED?
>> MY SUSPICION IS WE DON'T KNOW
ENOUGH YET.
IF YOU HAVE A KID WITH
CHALLENGES AND PROBLEMS, THERE'S
A TENT SEE TO GET INSULATED AT
TIMES AND FEEL LIKE YOU'RE
HANDLING IT OR FEEL OVERWHELMED
AND THE NOT KNOW NECESSARILY
WHAT TO DO.
WE DON'T KNOW ENOUGH INFORMATION
ABOUT THAT.
SUFFICE IT TO SAY, IF YOU HAVE
INDIVIDUALS UNSTABLE AND YOU
KNOW IT, IT'S PROBABLY A GOOD
IDEA TO RESTRICT THEIR ACCESS TO
FIREARMS WITHIN THEIR OWN HOME.
THE OTHER ISSUE THAT HAS BEEN
TALKED ABOUT ON THE SHOW IS
ACCESS TO FIREARMS BY PEOPLE WHO
REALLY ARE UNSTABLE OR HAVE
VIOLENT FANTASIES.
THESE INDIVIDUALS, WE NEED TO
HAVE A BETTER METHOD OF
RESTRICTING THEIR ACCESS TO
TOOLS OF DESTRUCTION.
>> AND, AGAIN, WE DON'T KNOW
ENOUGH ABOUT IN YOUNG MAN TO
KNOW WHAT LED UP TO THIS.
IN GENERAL HOW DO YOU TREAT THE
KIND OF ANGER THAT DOES END
UP -- IN PARTICULARLY YOUNG MEN
IT SEEMS TO ME WITH SORT OF THIS
UNBRIDLED ANGER.
THERE ARE LOTS OF ANGRY YOUNG
MEN.
THEY WRITE NOVELS ABOUT THIS.
IT'S A PART OF ADOLESCENCE IN
EARLY 20s, IS IT NOT?
>> THERE CAN BE SOME OF THAT,
BUT THE PEOPLE THAT DO THESE
KINDS OF ACTIONS TYPICALLY
IMMERSE THEMSELVES IN VIOLENT
STIMULATION, AND THEY'RE USUALLY
NOT OVERTLY ANGRY.
THERE'S THESE THEMES OF ANGER
THAT ARE CONVERTED INTO A
COGNITIVE OR MENTAL FANTASY OF
REVENGE THAT FINDS ITS WAY INTO
WHAT THEY TALK ABOUT, WHAT THEIR
INTERESTED IN, AND IT TENDS TO
BECOME AN OBSESSION WITH
VIOLENCE AS BEING THE ANTIDOTE
OR THE SOLUTION TO THEIR
PROBLEMS.
SO WHERE YOU SEE ANGER, THAT'S
ONE THING.
WHERE YOU SEE IT'S BEING
CONVERTED INTO AN ACTION PLAN
AND WHERE THEY START TO TAKE
STEPS TOWARDS THAT ACTION PLAN
AND IT SEEMS LIKE IT'S THE
ALL-ENCOMPASSING SOLUTION AND
DEVELOPING INTO THAT FOR THEM,
THAT'S WHERE WE HAVE A PROBLEM
AND THE NEED TO STEP IN.
IF YOU'RE NOT SURE ABOUT WHETHER
THE PERSON YOU'RE CONCERNED
ABOUT FITS THAT CATEGORY, BY ALL
MEANS SAY SOMETHING TO SOMEBODY
IN A POSITION TO FURTHER
INVESTIGATE.
THERE ARE EXPERTS THAT MAKE A
DIFFERENCE AND THESE PEOPLE ARE
STOPPED OR PUT INTO HELP OR A
SETTING WHERE THEY CAN NOT DO
ANY HARM TO ANYBODY ELSE.
>> FORENSIC PSYCHOLOGIST CHRIS
MA HANDY, THANK YOU FOR JOINING
ME THIS MORNING.
>> THANK YOU.
>> UP NEXT, A CHECK OF SOME
OTHER STORIES WE'RE FOLLOWING,
AND THEN PARENTING AND KIDS WHO
KILL.
NEW PRILOSEC OTC WILDBERRY
IS THE SAME FREQUENT HEARTBURN
TREATMENT AS PRILOSEC OTC.
NOW WITH A FANCY COATING
THAT GIVES YOU A BURST
OF WILDBERRY FLAVOR.
NOW WHY MAKE A FLAVORED
HEARTBURN PILL?
BECAUSE THIS IS AMERICA.
AND WE DON'T JUST
MAKE THINGS YOU WANT,
WE MAKE THINGS YOU
DIDN'T EVEN KNOW YOU WANTED.
LIKE A SPOON FORK.
SPRAY CHEESE.
AND JEANS MADE
OUT OF SWEATPANTS.
SO GRAB YOURSELF SOME
NEW PRILOSEC OTC WILDBERRY.
[ Male Announcer ]
ONE PILL EACH MORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBURN.
SATISFACTION GUARANTEED
OR YOUR MONEY BACK.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO OUR SPECIAL
STATE OF THE UNION COVERAGE FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE WANT TO GET BACK IN JUST A
SECOND TO THE SUBJECT OF HOW
PARENTS COPE WHEN THEIR KIDS
KILL.
FIRST, WE WANT TO GO OUR CNN'S
DANA BASH IN WASHINGTON.
SHE HAS A CHECK OF HEADLINES.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA APPEARS TO
READY TO NOMINATE SENATOR JOHN
KERRY AS THE NEXT SECRETARY OF
STATE.
A DEMOCRAT THAT SPOKE TO KERRY
TELLS CNN THE ANNOUNCEMENT COULD
COME THIS WEEK.
KERRY IS CURRENTLY THE CHAIRMAN
OF THE SENATE FOREIGN RELATIONS
COMMITTEE.
MANY COLLEAGUES ON BOTH SIDES OF
THE AISLE IN THE SENATE HAVE
EXPRESSED SUPPORT FOR KERRY.
HE'S LIKELY TO WIN SENATE
CONFIRMATION EASILY.
THE CURRENT SECRETARY OF STATE
IS RECOVERING FROM A CONCUSSION.
HILLARY CLINTON SUSTAINED THE
INJURY AFTER SHE FAINTED DURING
A BOUT WITH THE STOMACH FLU.
SHE'S BEING MON TOITORED BY DOCS
WHO RECOMMEND SHE TAKE THE WEEK
OFF.
SHE WILL NOT TESTIMONY THURSDAY
ON THE SEPTEMBER ATTACK ON THE
U.S. CONSULATE IN BENGHAZI.
>>> THE STATE DEPARTMENT IS
EXPECTED TO RECEIVE AN
INDEPENDENT ADVISORY REVIEW
BOARD'S REPORT TOMORROW.
THEY WILL RECEIVE IT ON
WEDNESDAY, AND THE STATE
DEPARTMENT IS ALSO EXPECTED TO
PRESENT RECOMMENDATIONS ON
IMPROVING SECURITY AT U.S.
EMBASSIES.
>>> A POTENTIAL BREAKTHROUGH ON
STALLED FISCAL CLIFF TALKS.
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER IS
OFFERING SOMETHING THAT HE AND
OTHER REPUBLICANS REALLY OPPOSE,
AND THAT IS RAISING TAX RATES ON
THE WEALTHIEST AMERICANS.
THAT'S THE CONDITION PRESIDENT
OBAMA HAS INSISTED ON FOR ANY
DEAL TO AVERT A FISCAL CLIFF,
WHICH BY THE WAY, IS A LITTLE
MORE THAN TWO WEEKS AWAY.
THE PRESIDENT WANTS TAX HIKES ON
INCOMES ABOVE $250,000.
CNN IS TOLD BOEHNER PROPOSED THE
INCREASE START AT INCOMES OF $1
MILLION IN EXCHANGE FOR THE
PRESIDENT AGREEING TO MORE
SIGNIFICANT SPENDING CUTS.
THOSE ARE THE HEADLINES AND BACK
TO CANDY CROWLEY IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
CANDY.
>> THANKS SO MUCH, DANA.
>>> UP NEXT, BLAME, SHAME, AND
MOVING BEYOND THE TERROR.
THE PARENTS OF KIDS WHO KILL.
WE'RE AT WALMART
WITH THE SIMMONS FAMILY.
HOW MUCH IS
YOUR CURRENT PHONE BILL?
FOUR SIXTEEN SEVENTY SIX
A MONTH!
OKAY, COME WITH ME --
WE'RE GONNA SAVE YOU MONEY.
WITH STRAIGHT TALK
AT WALMART,
YOU GET UNLIMITED TALK,
TEXT AND DATA
FOR ONLY $45 A MONTH
PER PHONE.
WOULD WE GET
THE SAME COVERAGE?
SAME COVERAGE
ON AMERICA'S BEST NETWORKS.
YOU SAVED $146.76
BY SWITCHING TO STRAIGHT TALK.
AWESOME!
NOW YOU CAN AFFORD
TO SHARE YOUR ALLOWANCE
WITH ME.
GET THE SEASON'S
HOTTEST SMARTPHONES
LIKE THE SAMSUNG GALAXY S2
AND GET STRAIGHT TALK
WITH UNLIMITED DATA
FOR JUST $45 A MONTH --
FROM AMERICA'S
GIFT HEADQUARTERS. WALMART.
♪
>>> JOINING ME NOW IS ANDREW
SALMON THE AUTHOR OF "FAR FROM
THE TREE."
YOU SAT DOWN, ANDREW, WITH THE
PARENTS OF COLUMBINE KILLER
DYLAN KLEBOLD.
WHILE EVER OTHER MOTHER WAS
PRAYING HER CHILD WAS SAFE, I
HAD TO PRAY THAT MINE WOULD DIE
BEFORE HE HURT ANYONE ELSE.
I SAW THE END PRODUCT OF MY
LIFE'S WORK.
I HAD CREATED AA MONSTER.
THIS IS FROM DYLAN'S MOTHER.
THAT MAKES ME -- I MEAN TO PRAY
FOR YOUR OWN SON TO DIE.
WHAT ELSE DID YOU LEARN FROM
TALKING TO THEM?
>> YOU KNOW, I THOUGHT BEFORE I
WENT OUT THERE THAT I WOULD MEET
THEM AND UNDERSTAND WHY.
IN TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS, WHY IS
THE QUESTION EVERYONE HAS, AND
THE BETTER I GOT TO KNOW THEM,
THE MORE MYSTIFIED I WAS.
THEY'RE KIND, GOOD, ADMIRABLE
PEOPLE.
SO THEY HAD CREATED THIS CHILD.
I THOUGHT THAT THAT ILLNESS THA
THAT CAUSED HIM TO DO THAT WAS A
STRANGE AND INEXPLICABLE ILLNESS
AS SOMEONE WHO HAS A SUDDEN
ONSET OF KIDNEY FAILURE OR
SOMETHING.
>> I KNOW YOU HAVE WRITTEN ABOUT
MENTAL HEALTH, AS WELL.
I LOVED YOUR BOOKS ON THAT.
I WONDER IF THAT ISN'T THE
CONCLUSION WHEN YOU DO MEET
THESE PARENTS AND YOU THINK,
WAIT, THAT'S ME.
THAT'S THE KIND, LOVING, COME
TALK TO ME ABOUT ANYTHING PARENT
I THINK I AM.
DID YOU COME AWAY WITH THAT?
>> I DID.
AND IT'S GIVEN ME A VERY
DIFFERENT ATTITUDE TOWARDS MY
OWN CHILDREN, WHO I FIND LOVELY
AND DELIGHTFUL IN EVERY POSSIBLE
WAY, BUT I RECOGNIZE HOW
UNKNOWABUNKNOW
ABLE OTHER PEOPLE ARE.
PEOPLE WANT IT THIS INFORMATION
ABOUT ADAM LANZA AND HOW COULD
HE DO IT AND SOMETIMES PEOPLE
KEEP SECRET AND YOU DON'T KNOW.
>> IT LEADS YOU ALMOST
INEVITABLY TO BRAIN CHEMISTRY?
>> I THINK IT LEADS TO BRAIN
CHEMISTRY.
WHEN IT GETS MORE SOPHISTICATED
WE'LL SEE IN WHAT IS GOING ON IN
THE BRAINS OF PEOPLE LIKE THAT.
>> THE FATHER OF EMILIE PARKER,
ROBBIE PARKER COMING OUT AND
TALKING ABOUT FORGIVENESS.
I WANT TO PLAY THE BRIEF CLIP OF
WHAT HE SAID.
>> OUR HEARTS AND OUR PRAYERS GO
OUT TO THEM.
THIS INCLUDES THE FAMILY OF THE
SHOOTER.
I CAN'T IMAGINE HOW HARD THIS
EXPERIENCE MUST BE FOR YOU.
AND I WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT OUR
FAMILY AND OUR LOVE AND OUR
SUPPORT GOES OUT TO YOU, AS
WELL.
>> THIS, IT WAS AN AMAZING ACT,
IN AND OF ITSELF, JUST TO BE
ABLE TO WALK OUT AND TALK AND
PUT TWO WORDS TOGETHER.
BUT DOES THAT SORT OF THING
HELP?
HOW DID YOU FIND DYLAN'S PARENTS
MOVED ON, BECAUSE THEY HAVE TO.
I KNOW THEY MOVED AWAY.
>> NO, THEY'RE STILL LIVING
THERE.
THEY SAID WE NEEDED TO STAY SOME
PLACE WHERE THERE WERE PEOPLE
WHO HAD KNOWN AND LOVED US AND
PEOPLE WHO HAD KNOWN AND LOVED
DYLAN AND THERE'S THE SENSE,
SOMEHOW, THAT WE WANT TO BLAME
PARENTS.
WE DON'T BLAME PARENTS FOR
AUTISM AND WE WANT TO BLAME
PARENTS FOR THE COMMISSION OF
THE CRIMES.
FOR TOM AND SUE, WHAT WAS SO
DIFFICULT IS THAT THEY HADN'T
KNOWN THEIR CHILD AND WHILE ALL
OF THE PEOPLE WHO WERE KILLED
LOST A CHILD, I MEAN, ALL THE
PARENTS OF THOSE PEOPLE AND THE
KLEBOLDS LOST NOT ONLY THEIR
CHILD, BUT THEIR UNDERSTANDING
OF THAT CHILD.
>> AND THEIR SENSE OF WHO THEY
WERE.
>> EXACTLY.
I REMEMBER SAYING TO THEM, WHAT
WOULD YOU ASK DYLAN IF HE WAS
HERE RIGHT NOW?
HIS FATHER SAID, I WOULD ASK HIM
WHAT HE WAS DOING AND HIS MOTHER
PAUSED AND SAID I WOULD ASK HIM
TO FORGIVE ME FOR BEING HIS
MOTHER AND NOT KNOWING WHAT WAS
GOING ON INSIDE HIS HEAD.
>> YOU TALK TO FORENSIC
PSYCHOLOGISTS, THEY SAY THERE
ARE SIGNS.
HERE PARENTS THOUGHT THEY KNEW
THEIR CHILD AND DIDN'T SEE ANY
SIGNS.
>> DIDN'T SEE ANY SIGNS.
I THINK IN LOOKING AT THIS
CURRENT SITUATION.
YOU HAVE TO LOOK AT THE FACT,
THE THING THAT MADE IT INTO HUGE
NEWS IS THE GHASTLY UNSPEAKABLE
AWFUL HOMICIDE, BUT IT WAS ALSO
A SUICIDE.
IF YOU'RE TRYING TO UNDERSTAND
THE PEOPLE WHO DO
MURDER/SUICIDE, YOU HAVE TO
START WITH THE SUICIDE.
WHAT WAS IT THAT WAS SO BROKEN
IN THEMSELVES THAT THEY WANTED
TO DESTROY THEMSELVES AND WHY
DID THEY NEED TO DO IT IN SUCH
AN AGGRESSIVE, OVERPOWERING AND
CRUEL FASHION.
AND WHILE WE'RE ALL MORE WORRIED
ABOUT WHY DID HE SHOOT UP THAT
SCHOOL, IF WE COULD BEGIN TO
UNDERSTAND WHY HE SHOT HIMSELF,
THAT WOULD BE THE FIRST STEP TO
GETTING SOME INSIGHT.
>> ANDREW SOLOMON, THANK YOU FOR
COMING ON THE SHOW.
>> THANK YOU, PLEASURE TO BE
HERE.
>>> NEXT, THE PRESIDENT AS
COMFORTER IN CHIEF.
FOR THE HOLI.
LOOK AT THAT PRICE.
THAT'S GREAT!
IF YOU FIND A LOWER
ADVERTISED PRICE,
WALMART WILL MATCH IT
AT THE REGISTER.
REALLY?
YEAH.
THERE YOU HAVE IT.
OH MY GOODNESS!
THAT'S THE WALMART
LOW PRICE GUARANTEE.
SEE FOR YOURSELF.
BRING IN YOUR LAST RECEIPT
AND SEE HOW MUCH
YOU CAN SAVE.
BE READY. WITH THE SEASON'S
TASTIEST BRANDS.
LIKE SEA PAK
SHRIMP SPRING ROLLS.
DELICIOUS HANDMADE ROLLS,
AUTHENTIC ASIAN TASTE.
WALMART HAS EVERYTHING YOU NEED
TO BE READY FOR HOLIDAY HOSTING.
WITH OUR LOW PRICE GUARANTEE
BACKED BY AD MATCH.
WALMART.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
>>> THANKS FOR WATCHING THIS
SPECIAL STATE OF UNION.
I'M CANDY CROWLEY AND I'LL BE
BACK HERE AT NOON EASTERN.
THIS ING THE PRESIDENT WILL BE
IN NEWTOWN TO MEET WITH THE
FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS.
THE NEED FOR A PRESIDENT TO PUT
WORDS TO A COLLECTIVE GRIEF IS A
FAMILIAR PART OF THE RHYTHM OF
TRAGEDIES THAT TEAR OPEN THE
SOUL OF A NATION.
WE LEAVE YOU WITH A LOOK AT
PRESIDENTS AS COMFORTER IN
CHIEFS.
>> "CHALLENGER" NOW HEADING DOWN
RANGE.
>> THE CREW OF THE SPACE SHUTTLE
"CHALLENGER" HONORED US.
WE WILL NEVER FORGET THEM NOR
THE LAST TIME WE SAW THEM, THIS
MORNING.
AS THEY PREPARED FOR THEIR
JOURNEY AND WAVED GOOD-BYE.
AND SLIPPED TO BONDS OF EARTH TO
TOUCH THE FACE OF GOD.
>> LET US LET OUR OWN CHILDREN
KNOW WE WILL STAND AGAINST THE
FORCES OF FEAR.
WHEN THERE IS TALK OF HATRED,
LET US STAND UP AND TALK AGAINST
IT.
WHEN THERE IS TALK OF VIOLENCE,
LET US STAND UP AND TALK AGAINST
IT.
IN THE FACE OF DEATH, LET US
HONOR LIFE.
>> YOU HAVE TO HELP US HERE.
TAKE CARE OF YOURSELVES AND YOUR
FAMILIES FIRST.
TAKE CARE OF THE SCHOOL NEXT.
BUT, REMEMBER, YOU CAN HELP
AMERICA HEAL.
AND IN SO DOING, YOU WILL SPEED
THE PROCESS OF HEALING FOR
YOURSELVES.
>> THE PICTURES OF AIRPLANES
FLYING INTO BUILDINGS, FIRES
BURNING, HUGE STRUCTURES
COLLAPSING HAVE FILLED US WITH
DISBELIEF, TERRIBLE SADNESS AND
A QUIET, UNYIELDING ANGER.
THESE ACTS OF MASS MURDER WERE
INTENDED TO