INTO CHAOS AND RETREAT, BUT THEY
ARE FAILED.
OUR COUNTRY IS STRONG.
>> THOSE WHO DIED HERE, THOSE
WHO SAVED LIFE HERE, THEY HELP
ME BELIEVE.
WE MAY NOT BE ABLE TO STOP ALL
EVIL IN THE WORLD, BUT I KNOW
THAT HOW WE TREAT ONE ANOTHER,
THAT'S ENTIRELY UP TO US.
AND I BELIEVE THAT FOR ALL OUR
IMPERFECTIONS WE ARE FULL OF
DECENCY AND GOODNESS AND THE
FORCES THAT DIVIDE US ARE NOT AS
STRONG AS THOSE THAT UNITE US.
>>> I'M WOLF BLITZER.
FAREED ZAKARIA "GPS" WILL NOT BE
SEEN THIS WEEKEND.
WE WANT TO WELCOME OUR VIEWERS
IN THE UNITED STATES AND AROUND
THE WORLD.
OVER THE PAST TWO DAYS, WE'VE
SEEN A FATHER TRY TO PUT HIS
IMMEASURABLE PAIN INTO WORDS.
>> MY FAMILY IS ONE OF THE
FAMILIES THAT LOST A CHILD
YESTERDAY.
MY DAUGHTER, EMILIE, WOULD BE
ONE OF THE FIRST ONES TO BE
STANDING AND GIVING HER LOVE AND
SUPPORT TO ALL THOSE VICTIMS.
BECAUSE THAT'S THE TYPE OF
PERSON SHE IS.
AS THE DEEP PAIN BEGINS TO
SETTLE INTO OUR HEARTS, WE FIND
COMFORT REFLECTING ON THE
INCREDIBLE PERSON THAT EMILIE
WAS.
>> WE'VE ALSO SEEN PARENTS
TRYING TO FIND WORDS TO EXPRESS
THEIR GRATITUDE AND THEIR
RELIEF.
>> WE'RE VERY LUCKY THAT ALL THE
CHILDREN, MY SON INCLUDED, HAD
THE PRESENCE OF MIND TO REACT
APPROPRIATELY AND THEY BASICALLY
RAN RIGHT NEXT TO THE GUY AND
OUT THE DOOR.
>> THERE WILL BE MORE WORDS,
THERE WILL BE MORE STORIES TODAY
AS NEWTOWN AND THE REST OF THE
NATION TRY TO MAKE SOME SENSE
OUT OF THIS TRAGEDY THAT TOOK
THE LIVES OF 20 CHILDREN.
I'M JOINED THIS HOUR BY CNN'S
SOLEDAD O'BRIEN.
SOLEDAD?
>> GOOD MORNING TO YOU, WOLF.
HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW RIGHT NOW.
THIS MORNING, CONNECTICUT'S
CHIEF MEDICAL EXAMINER WILL BE
PERFORMING AUTOPSIES ON THE
GUNMAN, ADAM LANZA AND ON HIS
MOTHER, AS WELL, WHO WAS KILLED
AT HER HOME.
THE RESULTS OF THOSE AUTOPSIES
WE'RE EXPECTING TO BE RELEASED
AT A NEWS CONFERENCE THAT WILL
BE HELD LATER TODAY.
ALSO TODAY, PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL
BE IN NEWTOWN.
HE WILL SPEAK AT A MEMORIAL
SERVICE.
BEFORE THAT SERVICE, HE WILL
MEET WITH MEMBERS OF THE
VICTIMS' FAMILIES AND ALSO WITH
FIRST RESPONDERS, AS WELL.
WE KNOW THE NAMES WERE MADE
PUBLIC LAST NIGHT.
12 GIRLS, 8 BOYS KILLED IN ALL.
EITHER 6 OR 7 YEARS OLD AND 6
ADULTS KILLED AT THE SCHOOL, AS
WELL.
THEY WERE ALL WOMEN.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER SAID THE
PRIMARY WEAPON IN THE MASSACRE
WAS A SEMI-AUTOMATIC RIFLE THAT
WAS FOUND AT THE SCENE AND EVERY
VICTIM HE EXAMINED, WHICH WERE
SEVEN VICTIMS, HAD BEEN HIT MORE
THAN ONCE.
ONE CASE 1 1 TI1 TIMES.
HE PENETRATED THE SCHOOL
BUILDING BY LITERALLY SHOOTING
HIS WAY INTO THE ENTRANCE WITH
AN ASSAULT WEAPON.
WOLF?
>> SOLEDAD, THE DAY BEFORE A
GUNMAN MASSACRED 20 SCHOOL
CHILDREN IN THEIR CLASSROOMS ALL
AGES 6 OR 7, FIRST GRADERS RIGHT
HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
LAWMAKERS IN MICHIGAN PASSED A
BILL THAT WOULD ALLOW PEOPLE TO
CARRY CONCEALED WEAPONS IN
SCHOOLS, DESPITE THE OBJECS OF
THE SCHOOL STATE BOARDS.
IN ILLINOIS THEY STRUCK DOWN A
BAN ON CARRYING CONCEALED
WEAPONS.
IN FLORIDA, OFFICIALS ANNOUNCED
THEY WOULD SOON ISSUE THEIR
MILLIONTH CONCEALED WEAPON AND
FIREARM LICENSE.
AS THE COUNTRY ABSORBS ANOTHER
MASS SHOOTING, PRESIDENT OBAMA
USED HIS WEEKLY SATURDAY ADDRESS
TO REPEAT HIS CALL FOR CHANGE.
>> ANY OF THESE NEIGHBORHOODS
COULD BE OUR OWN.
SO WE HAVE TO COME TOGETHER AND
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO TAKE
MEANINGFUL ACTION TO PREVENT
MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS FROM
HAPPENING, REGARDLESS OF
POLITICS.
>> BUT THAT WILL BE A TOUGH SELL
FOR SOME GUN CONTROL OPPONENTS.
>> THE SIMPLE FACTS ARE, GUNS
EXIST.
THEY ARE ESPECIALLY 1800
TECHNOLOGY.
THEY'RE EASY TO MAKE, THEY'RE
NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
THEY LAST SEVERAL HUMAN
LIFETIMES WITH MINIMAL
MAINTENANCE.
SO, SINCE GUNS EXIST AND WE
KNOW, FOR A FACT, THAT THE ONLY
WAY TO STOP AN EVIL PERSON LIKE
THE PERSON YOU WERE DISCUSSING
EARLIER IN THE SHOW IS TO SHOOT
HIM.
>> JOINING US NOW FROM THE TIME
WARNER CENTER IN NEW YORK
DEMOCRATIC REPRESENTATIVE JERRY
NADLER OF NEW YORK WHO SAYS THE
TIME FOR MORE STRICT GUN CONTROL
IS RIGHT NOW.
CONGRESSMAN, THANKS VERY MUCH
FOR COMING IN.
WHEN THE PRESIDENT SAYS WE NEED
"MEANINGFUL ACTION RIGHT NOW"
WHAT DO YOU WANT HIM TO DO?
>> WELL, I WANT THE PRESIDENT TO
TAKE THE LEADERSHIP AND USE THE
BULLY PULPIT OF THE PRESIDENCY
TO LEAD A CRUSADE FOR MEANINGFUL
AND STRONG GUN CONTROL
LEGISLATION.
YOU KNOW, THE UNITED STATES --
AND HE'S THE ONLY ONE THAT CAN
DO IT, REALLY.
WE KNOW GUN LOBBY HAS STRONG
SUPPORT IN CONGRESS BECAUSE
MEMBERS OF CONGRESS ARE
TERRIFIED OF THEIR ALLEGED
POLITICAL POWER.
BUT A PRESIDENT CAN LEAD A
CAMPAIGN AND CAN DIRECT THE
MORAL OF THE COUNTRY AND MEMBERS
OF CONGRESS OR SENATORS REFUSE
TO SUPPORT STRONG GUN CONTROL
LEGISLATION.
AND WE KNOW IT, WE'VE HEARD ALL
THE NONSENSE.
>> CONGRESSMAN, SORRY FOR
INTERRUPTING, BUT HOW
DISAPPOINTED ARE YOU THAT IN HIS
FIRST TERM THIS WAS NOT A HIGH
PRIORITY FOR HIM, IF A PRIORITY
AT ALL?
>> I DON'T WANT TO GET INTO
THAT.
WHAT I CARE ABOUT IS WHAT
HAPPENS NOW.
THE PRESIDENT HAD A LOT OF
THINGS ON HIS PLATE.
HE HAD A DEPRESSION AND
OBSTRUCTIONIST CONGRESS.
IF THE PRESIDENT STEPS UP AND
LEADS THE CRUSADE AND WE SAVE,
GOD KNOWS HOW MANY LIVES BY
GETTING SOMETHING DONE, THAT
WILL BE GREAT.
THAT WILL BE A MONUMENT TO HIS
ADMINISTRATION.
>> YOU'VE BEEN IN CONGRESS FOR A
LONG TIME, SO, WHAT'S REALISTIC?
WHAT DO YOU THINK, WHAT KIND OF
LEGISLATION CAN BE PASSED BY THE
SENATE AND THE HOUSE, THE
PRESIDENT WOULD SIGN IT INTO LAW
THAT IS REALISTIC GIVEN THE
OPPOSITION.
>> WELL, I THINK WE CAN GET LAWS
TO BAN AUTOMATIC WEAPONS AND NO
HUNTER NEEDS AN AUTOMATIC WEAPON
TO SHOOT AT BIRDS OR DEER OR
WHATEVER.
WE CAN BAN HIGH-CAPACITY
AMMUNITION CLIPS.
THAT HAVE NO USE EXCEPT BY THE
MILITARY OR FOR MASS MURDER.
WE CAN PASS LEGISLATION TO LIMIT
GUN TRAFFICKING, SO NO ONE, SO A
GUN SHOP CAN'T SELL MORE THAN A
SPECIFIED NUMBER OF GUNS AT A
TIME.
WE CAN BAN THE GUN SHOW
EXCEPTION.
AT A GUN SHOW, UNLIKE AT A GUN
STORE, YOU CAN SELL ANYTHING,
YOU CAN SELL AN AUTOMATIC RIFLE
AND YOU CAN SELL HIGH-CAPACITY
CLIPS TO ANYONE WITHOUT A
BACKGROUND CHECK.
NO ONE IN HIS RIGHT MIND THINKS
PEOPLE WITH MENTAL HEALTH
PROBLEMS OR PEOPLE ON THE
TERRORISM LIST OR PEOPLE WHO ARE
FELONS SHOULD BE ABLE TO GET
DEADLY WEAPONRY.
LET ME JUST SAY, I KNOW THAT
THERE WILL PROBABLY BE PEOPLE ON
THIS SHOW LATER OR MAYBE THERE
WERE WHO WILL SAY THAT GUNS
DON'T KILL PEOPLE, PEOPLE KILL
PEOPLE AND YOU SHOULD ARM MORE
PEOPLE AND THAT WILL STOP THE
CROOKS.
BUT THE FACT OF THE MATTER IS,
THERE WAS A MANIAC ON FRIDAY WHO
ATTACKED AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
CHINA WITH A KNIFE, NOT A GUN.
22 CHILDREN WERE INJURED.
NOBODY DIED.
WE HAVE 9,000, 1,146 MURDERS
WITH GUNS IN THE UNITED STATES
OR DEATHS IN THE UNITED STATES A
COUPLE YEARS AGO.
GERMANY HAD 158.
CANADA 173.
THE UNITED STATES HAS 15 TIMES
MORE THAN ANYBODY ELSE ON A
POPULPO
POPULATION BASIS.
THERE IS ONE REASON AND ONE
REASON ONLY, INSANE ATTITUDE
TOWARDS GUNS.
THE NRA SHOULD STOP, THEY WON'T.
WE SHOULD STOP THEM FROM BEING
ENABLERS OF MASS MURDER.
>> BEING THE NATIONAL RIFLE
ASSOCIATION.
CONGRESSMAN, THANKS VERY MUCH
FOR YOUR PERSPECTIVE.
>> THANK YOU.
>> JERRIEY EDJERRY.
>>> FORMER CHIEF ECONOMIST AT
THE U.S. SENTENCING COMMISSION
AND AUTHOR OF THE THIRD EDITION
OF THE BOOK "MORE GUNS, LESS
CRIMES."
THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR COMING
IN.
I'LL GIVE YOU A CHANCE TO
RESPOND.
THE UNITED STATES HAS A LOT MORE
MURDERS, YOU JUST HEARD FROM
CONGRESSMAN NADLER.
HE SAID IT'S BECAUSE THERE ARE
SO MANY GUNS THAT ARE SO EASIIL
AVAILABLE OUT THERE.
>> WELL, YOU LOOK AT THE MURDER
RATES IN THE OTHER COUNTRIES
WHETHER IF BE GERMANY HE JUST
MENTIONED OR OTHERS AND THEY HAD
LOWER MURDER RATES RELATIVE TO
THE UNITED STATES BEFORE THEY
HAD THE GUN CONTROL LAWS.
WHEN BRITAIN, OTHER COUNTRIES,
IRELAND, JAMAICA, OTHER PLACES
IMPOSED GUN BANS, MURDER RATES
WENT UP.
AMERICANS HAVE SEEN THAT IN
PLACES LIKE CHICAGO AND
WASHINGTON, D.C.
EVERY PLACE IN THE WORLD THAT WE
HAVE CRIME DATA BOTH BEFORE AND
AFTER A GUN BAN HAS GONE INTO
EFFECT, EVERY SINGLE PLACE HAS
SEEN AN INCREASE IN MURDERS
AFTER THE BAN HAS BEEN PUT IN
PLACE.
MANY TIMES, IT'S BEEN SEVERAL
FOLD OR MORE INCREASE IN
MURDERS.
A SIMPLE REASON FOR THAT.
THAT IS WHEN YOU BAN GUNS, IT'S
BASICALLY THE MOST LAW ABIDING
CITIZENS WHO TURN IN THEIR GUNS,
NOT THE CRIMINALS.
AND RATHER THAN MAKING MORE
DIFFICULT FOR CRIMINALS TO
COMMIT CRIME, YOU ACTUALLY MAKE
IT EASIER.
>> WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THE
LEGISLATION THAT THE CONGRESSMAN
WOULD LIKE TO SEE PASSED.
TIGHTENING UP SOME OF THESE
RESTRICTIONS.
MAKING IT MORE DIFFICULT, FOR
EXAMPLE, FOR MENTALLY ILL PEOPLE
TO GO OUT THERE AND BUY SOME
SEMI-AUTOMATIC WEAPONS.
>> WOLF, I GUESS YOU WOULD HAVE
CHALLENGED THEM A LITTLE BIT ON
CLAIMS ABOUT AUTOMATIC WEAPONS
AND SOME OF THE OTHER THINGS HE
WAS MAKING.
YOU KNOW THAT THESE AREN'T
INVOLVED IN ANY OF THESE TYPES
OF CASES THAT WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT HERE.
BUT THE POINT IS, WE'VE TRIED A
LOT OF THESE LAWS ALREADY IN THE
UNITED STATES.
WE HAD THE ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN.
THERE'S NO STUDY, NO ACADEMIC
STUDY BY AN ECONOMIST OR BY
CRIMINOLOGISTS THAT HAS SEEN
WHEN THE ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN,
THERE WAS ANY INCREASE IN MURDER
RATES.
YOU CAN GO FROM POLITICIANS FROM
DIANNE FEINSTEIN AND CHUCK
SCHUMER AND OTHERS WHO WERE
PREDICTING HUGE INCREASES IN
MURDERS AND ROBBERIES AFTER
SUNSETS.
ROBBERERALTIES ARE LOWER NOW
THAN THEY WOULD HAVE BEEN
OTHERWISE.
EVEN WHEN THE CLINTON
ADMINISTRATION PAID FOR
ACADEMICS TO GO LOOK AT THE
IMPACT OF THE ORIGINAL ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN IN 1994, THEY DID
NOT FIND ANY STATISTICAL
EVIDENCE THAT IT HAD IMPROVED
CRIME RATES IN ANY WAY.
AND, YOU KNOW, SO, WE'RE
TALKING --
>> LET ME INTERRUPT FOR A
SECOND, MR. LOTT.
HOLD ON FOR A SECOND.
THE DUSHMASTER A SEMI-AUTOMATIC
RIFLE THAT APPARENTLY KILLED ALL
THE KIDS AND THE TEACHERS IN THE
SCHOOL.
>> RIGHT.
SEMI-AUTOMATIC AND HE WAS SAYING
AUTOMATIC.
THERE IS A BIG DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN A MACHINE GUN AND
SOMETHING THAT IS A HUNTING
RIFLE.
LOOK, REGULAR CIVILIANS.
>> WHY DO PEOPLE NEED A
SEMI-AUTOMATIC BUSHMASTER TO GO
OUT AND KILL DEER?
>> LOOK, MOST HUNTING RIFLES ARE
SEMI-AUTOMATIC RIFLES.
OKAY.
PEOPLE USED SEMI-AUTOMATIC --
>> IS THE BUSHMASTER A HUNTING
RIFLE?
IS THE BUSHMASTER A HUNTING
>> RIGHT.
THE INSIDE GUTS OF IT IN TERMS
OF HOW IT FUNCTIONS IS A HUNTING
RIFLE.
THE OUTSIDE OF IT IS WHAT PEOPLE
GET UPSET ABOUT, BUT WHETHER --
WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT SOMEBODY
USING AN AK .47 IN ONE OF THESE
ATTACKS, NOT THE TYPE OF GUN
MILITARIES USE AROUND THE WORLD.
THIS IS A MILITARY VERSION.
YOU HAVE BEEN WORKING ON THIS
LONG ENOUGH, YOU KNOW THESE ARE
CIVILIAN VERSIONS OF THESE GUNS.
LOOK, WHEN CIVILIANS -- IT'S
VERY IMPORTANT FOR THEM TO HAVE
SEMI AUTOMATIC WEAPONS FOR
DEFENSE.
IF YOU HAD A SINGLE SHOTGUN AND
TWO CRIMINALS ATTACKING YOU OR
YOU MISSED THE FIRST TIME YOU
FIRED AT A CRIMINAL, YOU'D BE IN
A LOT OF TROUBLE AT THAT POINT.
SO, IF YOU WANT TO GO AND TALK
ABOUT BANNING THE VAST MAJORITY
OF GUNS, WHICH IS
SEMI-AUTOMATIC, FINE, WE CAN
TALK ABOUT THE COSTS AND
BENEFITS OF DOING THAT.
HERE'S THE BIG THING THAT NOBODY
IS TALKING ABOUT.
THAT IS, ALL THESE ATTACKS ARE
OCCURRING IN PLACES WHERE WE BAN
GUNS.
YOU KNOW, YOU GO AND LOOK AT THE
AURORA, COLORADO, SHOOTING.
THERE WERE SEVEN MOVIE THEATERS
WITHIN A 20-MINUTE DRIVE OF
THAT, OF WHERE THE KILLER LIVED.
ONLY ONE OF THE SEVEN HAD
POSTINGS BANNING CONCEALED
HANDGUN PERMITS.
HE DIDN'T GO TO THE MOVIE
THEATER CLOSEST TO HIS HOME.
HE DIDN'T GO TO THE LARGEST
MOVIE THEATER.
HE WENT TO THE ONLY ONE THAT
BANNED GUNS.
WHETHER IT'S THE PORTLAND MALL
SHOOTING EARLIER THIS WEEK OR
THE OTHER -- EVERY SINGLE ONE OF
THESE CASES BAN GUNS.
>> MR. LOTT, I HAVE TO INTERRUPT
YOU BECAUSE , UNFORTUNATELY, WE
ARE OUT OF TIME.
YOU MADE YOUR CASE, WE MADE YOUR
POINT.
I EXPECT THIS DEBATE OVER GUNS
IN THE UNITED STATES IS ONLY
JUST BEGINNING.
RIGHT NOW, ESPECIALLY PRESIDENT
WILL BE ON HIS WAY HERE TO
NEWTOWN IN A FEW HOURS.
I SUSPECT HE WILL GET INVOLVED
MUCH MORE ASSERTIVELY IN HIS
SECOND TERM OF ADMINISTRATION
THAN HE DID IN HIS FIRST TERM.
>>> WHEN WE RETURN, COMFORTING
THEIR FLOCK.
MY INTERVIEW WITH MEMBERS OF
NEWTOWN'S CLERGY.
MEMBERS OF THE CLERGY WHO WILL
BE WITH THE PRESIDENT TONIGHT.
>> THIS TIME, I THINK THAT'S ALL
THE CLERGY WE'RE TRYING TO OFFER
CARE TO WHOMEVER.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
THAT'S WHY WE'RE STANDING HERE
TODAY, REALLY, BECAUSE WE KNOW
WHAT'S IMPORTANT IS THAT WE'RE
UNITED IN OUR CARE FOR THIS
COMMUNITY.
Capella University understands
rough economic times
have led to an increase in
clinical depression.
Drug and alcohol abuse is up.
And those dealing with grief
don't have access to the
professional help they need.
When you see these issues, do
you want to walk away or
step up?
With a degree in the field of
Counseling or Psychology from
Capella University, you'll have
the knowledge to make
a difference in the lives of
others.
Let's get started at
CAPELLA.EDU
PROGRESSIVE DIRECT AND OTHER
CAR INSURANCE COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
CALL OR CLICK TODAY.
he opened up
Jake's very private world.
At first, Jake's family
thought they saved Ziggy,
but his connection with Jake
has been a lifesaver.
For a love this strong,
his family only feeds him Iams.
Compared to other
leading brands,
it has 50% more
animal protein...
...to help keep Ziggy's body
as strong as a love
that reaches further
than anyone's words.
Iams. Keep Love Strong.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN DIARRHEA HITS,
KAOPECTATE STOPS IT FAST.
POWERFUL LIQUID RELIEF
SPEEDS TO THE SOURCE.
FAST.
[ Male Announcer ]
STOP THE UH-OH FAST
WITH KAOPECTATE.
>>> HEARTBREAKI ING IMAGES HEREN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, AS WE
CONTINUE OUR SPECIAL COVERAGE.
SOLEDAD O'BRIEN IS WITH US THIS
HOUR AND SHE'LL BE WITH US NEXT
HOUR, AS WELL.
WE'RE WATCHING WHAT IS GOING ON
AWAITING THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES.
HE'LL BE COMING HERE IN A FEW
HOURS FOR AN INTERFAITH VIGIL
THAT WILL BE TAKING PLACE.
>>> MEANWHILE, A SOMBER
CANDLELIGHT VIGIL BECAUSE HELD
LAST NIGHT TO BEGIN THE HEALING,
IF THAT IS AT ALL POSSIBLE.
I SAT DOWN WITH THE REVEREND
MATTHEW CREVIN.
>> BOTH OF YOU, RABBI AND
REVEREND, YOU HAVE BEEN SPENDING
TIME WITH FAMILY MEMBERS.
>> IT IS THE WORST TRAGEDY THAT
I'VE SEEN IN MY LIFE AND VERY
HARD TO CONSOLE A PARENT THAT
JUST DISCOVERED THAT THEIR
CHILDREN WERE AMONGST THE
VICTIMS.
>> REVEREND, YOU MET WITH
PARENTS WHO LOST KIDS.
>> YES.
WELL, WE WERE BOTH THERE
YESTERDAY IN THE FIREHOUSE WITH
THE FAMILIES DURING THAT WHOLE
PROCESS.
AND IT WAS JUST INDESCRIBABLE IN
TERMS OF THE GRIEF AND THE
WAITING AND TRYING TO BE PRESENT
TO THEM AND ALSO TO MANY OF THE
FOLKS THAT EMERGENCY SERVICES
AND POLICE OFFICERS SXU S AND O
WHO WERE JUST FEELING THE LOSS
AND THE SORROW OF THE MAGNITUDE
THAT WAS HAPPENING.
>> RABBI, ONE MOMENT YESTERDAY
WHEN YOU WERE IN THE FIREHOUSE
WITH THOSE FAMILIES THAT STANDS
OUT THAT YOU'LL NEVER FORGET IN
YOUR LIFE?
>> YES, SOME IMAGES THAT'S WHEN
THE NEWS CAME FROM THE GOVERNOR
THAT THE CHILDREN DID NOT MAKE
IT AND THE WAILING OF THE
PARENTS AND JUST SORT OF THE
GROPING AND TRYING TO REACH FOR
SOMETHING INTANGIBLE.
HORRIFIC SCENE.
>> YOU WERE THERE, TOO?
>> I WAS THERE, TOO.
IT WAS HOLY GROUND AND AS PEOPLE
HAVE TALKED TO ME AND ASKED ME
ABOUT IT, I TYPICALLY TELL
PEOPLE IT WAS HOLY GROUND AND I
HONOR THE HOLINESS OF THAT PLACE
AND SPACE AND THE PEOPLE THAT
WERE THERE, AS BEST I'M ABLE.
IT'S SOMETHING YOU NEVER WANT TO
BE IN A ROOM LIKE THAT EVER
AGAIN, BUT IN THE TRAGEDY, THERE
IS THIS SENSE OF THE HOLINESS OF
IT.
JUST UNMITIGATED LOSS AND
TRAGEDY AND HONORING THAT AND
HONORING THOSE FAMILIES IN THEIR
GRIEF.
>> WE NEED TO HAVE A CULTURE OF
PEACE AND SO MANY OF THE YOUNG
GAMES THAT WE HAVE AS CHILDREN
AT VERY YOUNG AGES IS ABOUT WAR
AND KILLING AND WE CAN MAKE,
WE'RE AN INTELLIGENT COUNTRY, WE
CAN MAKE WONDERFUL GAMES THAT
HAVE TO DO WITH PEACEMAKING AND
DIPLOMACY AND IT DOESN'T TAKE
ANY INTELLIGENCE TO PULL A
TRIGGER.
>> WHAT ARE YOU SUGGESTING, THE
SHOOTER IN THIS PARTICULAR CASE
GREW UP IN A CULTURE OF
VIOLENCE?
>> YES, THAT OUR ENTIRE
CIVILIZATION IS TOO INUNDATED
WITH THE CULTURE OF VIOLENCE.
THAT THERE CAN BE AN INCENTIVE
AND A FUN GAME THAT HAS TO DO
WITH LEARNING ABOUT OTHER PEOPLE
AND THE WORLD AND DEALING WITH
GRIEVANCES THROUGH ACTIVE DIP  M
DIPLOMACY.
>> SO MANY PEOPLE HAVE SAID TO
ME, REVEREND AND RABBI, HOW CAN
GOD ALLOW SOMETHING LIKE THIS TO
HAPPEN?
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
>> ONE OF THE THINGS I FIRST SAY
IN THIS MOMENT IS THAT THIS IS
NOT THE MOMENT TO ANSWER THAT
QUESTION.
AT LEAST NOT TO THE FAMILIES
THAT ARE IN GRIEF.
I THINK THERE ARE ANSWERS.
THERE ARE ANSWERS FROM MY
TRADITION THAT SPEAK TO
SUFFERING AND HOW SUFFERING CAN
BE TRANSFORMATIVE.
HOW AS A CHRISTIAN I UNDERSTAND
THAT THERE ARE WAYS IN WHICH WE
CAN TRANSFORM AND BE TRANSFORMED
IN THE MIST OF SUFFERING.
THAT'S NOT A QUESTION I TRY TO
ANSWER TODAY BECAUSE PEOPLE
DON'T NEED TO HEAR WHAT BECOMES
AN OVERSIMPLISTIC ANSWER TO
SOMETHING THAT IS SO PROFOUND.
>> WHAT WILL BE THE CENTRAL
MESSAGE THAT YOU TELL YOUR
CONGRUGNTS TOMORROW MORNING?
>> I WILL BE PREACHING A MESSAGE
THAT EVEN IN THE MIDST OF
DARKNESS, THERE IS LIGHT.
IT'S TRAGIC THAT WE ARE IN THE
MIDST OF THE SEASON FOR US AS
CHRISTIANS, WHICH IS
CHRISTMASTIME AND ADVENT AND
IT'S A HOLY TIME FOR US, BUT WE
ALSO KNOW THAT IN THE MIDST OF A
SEASON THAT SO OFTEN WE
ASSOCIATE WITH JOY AND MERRIMENT
THAT IT'S ALSO A SEASON OF
DARKNESS.
IN FACT, THE GOSPEL OF JOHN
TELLS US THAT THE LIGHT SHINES
IN THE DARKNESS AND THE DARKNESS
DOES NOT OVERCOME IT.
I WILL BE PREACHING A MESSAGE
THAT WE KNOW THE LIGHT OF GOD IS
WITH US AND THAT WE CAN BE
SUSTAINED IN THAT AND WE CAN SEE
THAT LIGHT IN EACH OTHER AND
DRAW FROM THAT LIFE THAT IS A
PART OF OUR FAITH.
>> THE MOST IMPORTANT THING THAT
WE CAN DO AS A REACTION TO THIS
IS TO THRIVE.
THE ENEMY IS THE HORRIBLE EVENT
AND THE BANQUET IS THE
CONTINUING OR THRIVING IN LIFE.
I LIVED IN ISRAEL FOR TEN YEARS
AND I SAW THE WAY THAT THE
ISRAELIS WOULD PICK UP AND GO
RIGHT TO THE SPOT WHERE
SOMETHING TERRIBLE HAPPENED AND
THE MESSAGE WAS WE CARRY ON AND
WE WILL CARRY ON.
WE HAVE GREAT SCHOOLS IN
NEWTOWN.
THIS WAS AN ISOLATED INCIDENT.
THIS EVENT DOESN'T DEFINE US.
WE WILL CONTINUE TO HAVE GREAT
SCHOOLS AND BE THE GREAT
COMMUNITY.
MATTHEW AND I ARE GREAT FRIENDS
AND ALL OF THE CLERGY ARE GREAT
FRIENDS AND WE WILL RECOVER.
>> RABBI, REVEREND, THANKS SO
MUCH.
>> THANK YOU, WOLF.
>>> THIS JUST IN.
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE,
THEY WILL HOLD A NEWS CONFERENCE
SOME TIME IN THE NEXT HOUR.
WE, OF COURSE, WILL BRING THAT
TO YOU LIVE WHEN THAT HAPPENS.
WE'RE EXPECTING NEW INFORMATION
FROM THE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE ON THIS ENTIRE KILLING
AND WHAT HAPPENED.
WHEN WE RETURN, MUCH MORE OF
WHAT'S GOING ON, INCLUDING THE
HEALING PROCESS.
>> AS WE MOVE ON FROM WHAT
HAPPENED HERE, WHAT HAPPENED TO
SO MANY PEOPLE LET IT NOT TURN
INTO SOMETHING THAT DEFINES US.
BUT SOMETHING THAT INSPIRES US
TO BE BETTER, TO BE MORE
COMPASSIONATE AND MORE HUMBLE
PEOPLE.
CAN I HELP YOU?
I HEARD YOU GUYS CAN SHIP GROUND
FOR LESS THAN THE UPS STORE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I'VE LEARNED THE ONLY WAY TO GET
A HOLIDAY DEAL IS TO CAMP OUT.
YOU KNOW WE'VE BEEN OPEN
ALL NIGHT.
IS THIS A TRICK
TO GET MY SPOT?
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SAVE ON GROUND SHIPPING
AT FEDEX OFFICE.
>>> IN THE WAKE OF FRIDAY'S
SHOOTING, STUDENTS AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL ARE BOUND TO
HAVE LOTS OF QUESTIONS THAT
COULD BE VERY CHALLENGING FOR
THEIR PARENTS TO ANSWER.
JOINING US THIS MORNING FROM
TIME WARNER CENTER IS DR. SUSAN
LIPKIN.
A SICIOLOGIST WHO SPECIALIZED IN
SCHOOL.
SUSAN, IF I CAN, I'D LIKE TO
START WITH YOU.
HOW DO YOU POSSIBLY REASSURE
CHILDREN.
THOSE CHILDREN HERE IN NEWTOWN,
THOSE CHILDREN WHO EXPERIENCED
SOMETHING HORRIFIC AND EVEN
CHILDREN WHO ARE NOT HERE AND
ACROSS THE COUNTRY THAT THEIR
SCHOOLS ARE SAFE WHEN THE
REALITY IS SOMETHING TERRIBLE
HAPPENED.
>> THE MOST IMPORTANT THING IS
TO TALK TO THE CHILD AT THEIR
LEVEL.
TO GET THEM TO TALK, TO PLAY, TO
DRAW OUT EVERYTHING THAT IS IN
THEIR MIND SO YOU UNDERSTAND
WHAT LEVEL THEY ARE AT AND AT
THAT POINT YOU HAVE TO REASSURE
THEM.
THE MOST IMPORTANT THING IS FOR
THE PARENTS' DEMEANOR TO BE
CALM, NOT TO BE ANXIOUS.
NOT TO BE CONSTANTLY WATCHING
THE NEWS AND TO FEEL SECURE IN
THEMSELVES BECAUSE THE CHILDREN
WILL MODEL THE FEELINGS THAT
THEY'RE GETTING FROM THEIR
PARENTS.
>> WHEN I TALKED TO SOME OF THE
PARENTS HERE WHOSE CHILDREN WERE
LITERALLY ABLE TO GET OUT OF
THEIR CLASSROOMS, THEY WERE
GOING TO GO FOR PSYCHOLOGICAL
HELP.
WHAT ABOUT PEOPLE, AGAIN, WHO
WERE NOT NECESSARILY IMMEDIATELY
INVOLVED IN THE SITUATION.
HOW WILL THEY DEAL WITH THE
PTSD, WOULD THEY EVEN EXPERIENCE
PTSD JUST BY BEING NEAR OR EVEN
NOT SO CLOSE TO THE SITUATION?
>> IT IS POSSIBLE THAT THEY WILL
EXPERIENCE MANY OF THE SYMPTOMS
OF STRESS AND MAYBE
POST-TRAUMATIC STRESS.
THAT WILL HAPPEN FOR THE FIRST
COUPLE OF WEEKS AND EVENTUALLY
IT WILL DIE DOWN AND IF IT DOES
NOT, THEN YOU SEEK PROFESSIONAL
CARE.
WE WOULD BE LOOKING FOR CHILDREN
AND ADULTS WHO HAVE PROBLEMS
SLEEPING, WHO HAVE PSYCHOSEMATIC
SYMPTOMS LIKE HEADACHES AND
STOMACH ACHES AND WHO WOULD
REFUSE TO SEPARATE AND DO NORMAL
ACTIVITIES.
REALLY IMPORTANT TO GET BACK TO
YOUR NORMAL ROUTINE AND GET BACK
TO SCHOOL AS QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE
FOR CHILDREN ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
>> SO, KEN, LET'S TALK MORE
SPECIFICALLY ABOUT THE SCHOOL.
WE NOW KNOW THAT THE SHOOTER WAS
ABLE TO BASICALLY SHOOT HIS WAY
INTO THE SCHOOL.
IS IT POSSIBLE TO MAKE A SCHOOL
SAFE WITHOUT HAVING IT BE BEHIND
BARS, ESSENTIALLY?
>> WE DON'T NEED TO TEACH
KINDERGARTNERS TO THROW PENCILS
AN ARMED INTRUDERS.
BUILDING RELATIONSHIPS WITH KIDS
AND KNOWING WHAT'S GOING ON IN
YOUR COMMUNITY WITH FAMILIES AND
HAVING BASIC SECURITY MEASURES,
LIKE WE SAW AT THE SCHOOL WITH
CAMERA BUZZER INTERCOM AND MAKE
SURE THAT YOUR STAFF IS TRAINED.
THE BEST LINE OF DEFENSE IS A
WELL-TRAINED, HIGHLY ALERT STAFF
AND STUDENT BODY, NOT TECHNOLOGY
OR EQUIPMENT, BUT EQUIPMENT
BEHIND IT.
>> BUT IT SOUNDS LIKE THEY HAD
ALL OF THAT.
THAT SCHOOL SECURITY SYSTEM WAS
PUT IN PLACE BY THE NEW SCHOOL
PRINCIPAL, SHE IS NOW DEAD.
THEY WERE VERY AGGRESSIVE IN
KNOWING THEIR STUDENTS.
>> SOME SITUATIONS YOU CAN'T
PREVENT.
BUT WHAT WE EXPECT AS PARENTS IS
TWO THINGS.
NUMBER ONE, SCHOOLS TO TAKE
STEPS TO REDUCE THE RISKS.
THE SECURITY MEASURES AND
TRAINING OF YOUR STAFF AND THE
LOCKDOWN DRILLS AND, TWO, BEING
PREPARED TO RESPOND WHEN AN
INCIDENT HAPPENS.
IF WE SAW A PRINCIPAL AND A
PSYCHOLOGIST RUN TO THE GUNMAN
TO TRY TO SAVE THEIR KIDS.
THAT'S SOMETHING I DON'T KNOW IF
WE CAN TRAIN PEOPLE TO DO, BUT
SOMETHING VERY MUCH IN THE
HEARTS OF ALL OF OUR EDUCATORS
TODAY.
WE DO THE BEST WE CAN AND WE
REDUCE THE RISKS AND WE TRAIN
PEOPLE TO RESPOND TO MINIMIZE
OUR LOSSES AND WE PLAN FOR THE
WORST AND PREPARE AND PRAY FOR
THE BEST.
>> THERE HAVE BEEN GUN LOBBYISTS
WHO HAVE BOTH WRITTEN AND BEEN
ON TELEVISION SHOWS TALKING
ABOUT HOW IF PEOPLE INSIDE THE
SCHOOL HAD BEEN ARMED, THAT THE
END RESULT COULD HAVE BEEN LESS
HORRIFIC THAN WHAT THEY ARE
EXPERIENCING HERE NOW.
YOU'VE, OBVIOUSLY, BEEN IN THE
SECURITY BUSINESS FOR A LONG
TIME AS IT RELATES TO SCHOOLS.
HAVE YOU SEEN ANY EVIDENCE OF
THAT?
>> WE HAVE SCHOOL RESOURCE
OFFICERS, POLICE OFFICERS WHO
ARE IN OUR SCHOOLS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY, NOT ALL SCHOOLS, BUT
SOME, AND WE CERTAINLY SUPPORT
THAT.
BUT TEACHERS WANT TO BE ARMED
WITH BACKPACKS OR WITH BOOKS,
BO
BOOKBAGS, COMPUTERS, TECHNOLOGY.
THEY DON'T WANT BULLETPROOF
BACKPACKS AND ARMED TO SHOOT.
WE NEED TO NOT POLITES IS THIS
ISSUE AT A TIME WHEN WE LOST
KIDS.
>> SUSAN, WE KNOW THIS YOUNG
MAN, THE SHOOTER, WE HAVE BEEN
CALLING HIM, WAS DISTURBED.
DESCRIPTIONS BY FAMILY MEMBERS,
AS WELL.
A LOT OF DETAILS STILL YET TO
BEKNOWNBE
OWN ABOUT HIM.
HOW DO YOU DEAL WITH SOMEONE WHO
IS CONSIDERED TO BE DISTURBED
AND POSSIBLY DANGEROUS AND WE
KNOW THAT MENTAL HEALTH
RESOURCES ARE HARD FOR FAMILIES
TO GET TO.
WE KNOW THAT GUNS ARE READILY
AVAILABLE IN THIS COUNTRY.
HOW DO YOU, HOW DO YOU STOP THAT
INTERSECTION, WHICH IS,
OBVIOUSLY, A DEADLY INTERSECTION
HAPPENING?
>> IT SEEMS TO BE IMPOSSIBLE.
IN MANY WAYS OUR MENTAL HEALTH
SYSTEM IS BROKEN.
WE NEED COMMUNITY SERVICES SO
THAT PEOPLE CAN BE REPORTED.
THAT THERE IS A 24/7 HOTLINE FOR
PEOPLE WHO ARE UNSTABLE AND, FOR
EXAMPLE, THAT THE PRINCIPAL
MIGHT HAVE REPORTED THE INCIDENT
THAT HAPPENED A COUPLE DAYS
BEFORE AND HAVE SOMEBODY TO
INVESTIGATE.
WE DON'T HAVE THOSE SERVICES
NOW.
AND THAT IS SOMETHING THAT WE
NEED TO DEVELOP.
>> DR. SUSAN LIPKIN AND KEN
TRUMP, THANK YOU FOR TALKING
WITH ME THIS MORNING.
WE CERTAINLY APPRECIATE YOUR
INSIGHT.
AS WOLF MENTIONED A FEW MOMENTS
AGO, WE'RE WAITING FOR THIS NEWS
CONFERENCE.
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
HAVE BEEN DOING A GREAT JOB
COMING UP TO UPDATE US.
WE ARE EXPECTING IT BETWEEN
11:00 A.M. EASTERN TIME AND
11:30.
>>> AHEAD, WE'LL TAKE A CLOSER
LOOK AT THIS KILLER AND ANSWER
THE QUESTION THAT MANY ARE
ASKING, WHICH IS WHY.
THAT'S STRAIGHT AHEAD.
WE'RE BACK IN JUST A MOMENT.
mm .
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
MEMORIALS LIKE THE ONE YOU'RE
LOOKING AT RIGHT HERE DOT MANY
OF THE CORNERS IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THEY'VE BEEN SET UP WHERE PEOPLE
LEAVE VOTIVE CANDLES OR NOTES OR
DOLLS OR TEDDY BEARS.
THIS TOWN IS HURTING.
PEOPLE HERE ARE EXPERIENCING A
VERY, VERY DEEP GRIEF AND IT IS
A GRIEF THAT WE ARE SURE THE
PRESIDENT WILL TALK ABOUT AS HE
MAKES HIS WAY HERE TO TALK TO
FAMILY MEMBERS AND FIRST
RESPONDERS AND TAKE PART IN A
VIGIL THAT WILL BE HELD TONIGHT.
WE WANT TO GET TO DANA BASH IN
WASHINGTON, D.C., WITH A CHECK
OF THE HEADLINES THIS MORNING.
DANA, GOOD MORNING.
>> GOOD MORNING, SOLEDAD.
THERE IS A POTENTIAL
BREAKTHROUGH IN STALLED FISCAL
CLIFF TALKS.
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER IS
OFFERING SOMETHING HE AND OTHER
REPUBLICANS OPPOSE.
RAISING TAX RATES ON THE
WEALTHIEST AMERICANS.
THAT'S A CONDITION PRESIDENT
OBAMA HAS INSISTED MUST BE PART
OF ANY DEAL TO AVERT THE FISCAL
CLIFF, WHICH IS A LITTLE MORE
THAN TWO WEEKS AWAY.
THE PRESIDENT WANTS TAX HIKES OF
INCOMES ABOVE $250,000.
THE INCREASE STARTS AT INCOMES
OF $1 MILLION IN EXCHANGE FOR
THE PRESIDENT AGREEING TO MORE
SIGNIFICANT SPENDING CUTS.
>>> AND SECRETARY OF STATE
HILLARY CLINTON IS RECOVERING
FROM A CONCUSSION.
SHE SUSTAINED THE INJURY AFTER
FAINTING DURING A BOUT WITH THE
STOMACH FLU.
CLINTON IS BEING MONITORED BY
DOCTORS WHO RECOMMEND THAT SHE
TAKE THE WEEK OFF.
AS A RESULT, SHE WILL NOT
TESTIFY AT THIS WEEK'S
MUCH-ANTICIPATED CONGRESSIONAL
HEARING ON SEPTEMBER'S DEADLY
ATTACK ON THE U.S. CONSULATE IN
BENGHAZI.
>>> ON THE NOTE OF TALKING ABOUT
THE STATE DEPARTMENT, PRESIDENT
OBAMA DOES APPEAR SET TO
NOMINATE SENATOR JOHN KERRY AS
HILLARY CLINTON'S SUCCESSOR.
JOINING ME NOW FOR MORE ON THIS,
CNN FOREIGN AFFAIRS REPORTER
ELISE.
THE BIGGEST OPEN SECRET IN
WASHINGTON, ONCE SUSAN RICE TOOK
HER NAME OUT OF THE RUNNING.
JOHN KERRY WOULD BE UP THERE.
>> JOHN KERRY MADE NO SECRET FOR
THE LAST SEVERAL YEARS,
ACTUALLY, THAT HE WOULD LOVE THE
JOB.
ON CAPITOL HILL YOU KNOW THAT
SENATORS HAVE SAID THAT HE WOULD
BE EASILY CONFIRMED.
>> THAT'S RIGHT BECAUSE OF
REPUBLICANS AND DEMOCRATS SEE
HIM AS SOMEBODY WHO WOULD BE
GOOD AT THE JOB AND, AS YOU
SAID, HE'S LOBBIED FOR IT.
BUT WHAT IS GOING TO BE
INTERESTING, ELISE, THIS COMING
WEEK WE TALKED ABOUT THE HEARING
IS GOING TO HAPPEN ON BENGHAZI,
HILLARY CLINTON IS NOT GOING TO
BE THERE, BUT JOHN KERRY IS THE
SENATE FOREIGN RELATIONS CHAIR.
HE IS STILL GOING TO CHAIR THAT
HEARING.
>> SECRETARY CLINTON TAKING THE
WEEK OFF TO RECUPERATE.
HER DEPUTY WILL BE TESTIFYING
FOR THIS INDEPENDENT ADVISORY
BOARD ON THE EVENTS IN BENGHAZI.
ALSO BE A CLOSED BRIEFING ON THE
HILL BY MEMBERS OF THE ADVISORY
BOARD.
NOW, GIVES JOHN KERRY KIND OF
ONE LAST CHANCE TO SHOW SOME
LEADERSHIP BEFORE HE HEADS OVER
FOR HIS CONFIRMATION HEARINGS.
YOU KNOW, JOHN KERRY REALLY,
ALTHOUGH SUSAN RICE MIGHT HAVE
BEEN THE PRESIDENT'S FIRST
CHOICE, I THINK NOW THE
ADMINISTRATION IS COMING AROUND
TO THE IDEA THAT SENATOR KERRY
IS VERY WILDLY RESPECTED
INTERNATIONALLY ON HIS OWN
RIGHT.
HE HAS DONE A LOT OF KIND OF
MISSIONS ON BEHALF OF THE
ADMINISTRATION AND HE'S VERY
CLOSE TO AFGHAN PRESIDENT HAR
MIDKARZAI AND THE PAKISTNIS.
HE'S ALSO WITH THE POLICY OF
ENGAGEMENT EARLY ON IN THE
ADMINISTRATION HE TRIED TO REACH
OUT TO SYRIAN PRESIDENT ASSAD.
HE IS REGRETTING THAT NOW, OF
COURSE.
>> WE'LL SEE IF THE PRESIDENT
WAITS TO NOMINATE HIM BECAUSE OF
WHAT HAPPENED IN CONNECTICUT,
BUT WE ASSUME IT WILL HAPPEN
THIS WEEK.
>>> NOW WE'LL GO BACK TO SOLEDAD
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
SOLEDAD?
>> DANA, THANKS VERY MUCH.
>>> WE'LL TALK AHEAD THIS
MORNING ABOUT THE VERY DIFFICULT
JOB FOR LAW ENFORCEMENT IN THIS
CASE.
FINDING A KILLER AMID A SCHOOL
FULL OF CHILDREN.
>> ON AND OFF DUTY TROOPERS
RESPONDED TO THE SCHOOL AND WITH
NEWTOWN POLICE IMMEDIATELY UPON
ARRIVAL ENTERED THE SCHOOL AND
BEGAN A COMPLETE ACTIVE SHOOTER
SEARCH OF THE BUILDING.
THAT INCLUDED CHECKING EVERY
DOOR, EVERY CRACK, EVERY
CREVICE, EVERY CORNER OF THAT
SCHOOL.
EVACUATE AS QUICKLY AND AS
EFFICIENTLY AS POSSIBLE ANY AND
ALL STUDENTS AND FACULTY IN THE
SCHOOL.
Again?
It's embarrassing
It's embarrassing!
We can see you Carl.
We can totally see you.
Come on you're better than
this...all that prowling around.
Yeah, you're the
king of the jungle.
Have you thought about going
vegan Carl?
HAHAHA!!
You know folks who save hundreds
of dollars by
switching to GEICO
sure are happy.
How happy are they Jimmy?
Happier than antelope with
night-vision goggles.
Nice!
Get happy. Get GEICO.
Fifteen minutes could save you
fifteen percent or more.
♪ OOH BABY,
CAN I DO FOR YOU TODAY? ♪
[ Female Announcer ] NEED HELP
KEEPING YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE?
ALIGN CAN HELP.
ONLY ALIGN HAS BIFANTIS,
A PATENTED PROBIOTIC
THAT NATURALLY HELPS MAINTAIN
YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE.
TRY ALIGN TO HELP RETAIN
A BALANCED DIGESTIVE SYSTEM.
TRY THE #1 GASTROENTEROLOGIST
RECOMMENDED PROBIOTIC.
ALIGN.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO OUR SPECIAL
COVERAGE HERE ON CNN.
I'M WOLF BLITZER HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE EXPECT FAIRLY SOON THE
NEWTOWN STATE POLICE TO HOLD A
CONFERENCE HERE IN NEWTOWN.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT THE
MICROPHONES BEING SET UP RIGHT
NOW.
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE WILL
UPDATE US ON THE INVESTIGATION.
PRESIDENT OBAMA ALSO WILL BE
HERE IN NEWTOWN LATER THIS
AFTERNOON TO THANK FIRST
RESPONDERS TO MEET WITH SOME OF
THE VICTIMS' FAMILIES.
HE'LL ALSO SPEAK AT THIS
EVENING'S INTERFAITH VIGIL
STARTING AT 7:00 P.M. EASTERN.
WE'LL HAVE LIVE COVERAGE, OF
COURSE, OF THE INTERFAITH
INDIVIDUALVIGIL.
WE LEARNED THIS MORNING OF THE
AUTOPSIES OF THE GUNMAN AND HIS
MOTHER.
MORE INFORMATION ON THAT COMING
UP.
>>> WHEN NEWTOWN POLICE STORMED
INTO SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL HERE IN THE SMALL
COMMUNITY, ILLUSTRATED A SHIFT
IN THE TACTICAL APPROACH THAT
LAW ENFORCEMENT HAS TAKEN IN
LIGHT OF THE COLUMBINE SHOOTING,
SOME 13 YEARS AGO.
JOINING US NOW FOR A CLOSER LOOK
AT HOW LAW ENFORCEMENT IS
DEALING WITH IT, WHAT HAS,
UNFORTUNATELY, BECOME A TRAGIC
AND SAD CHAPTER IN AMERICA'S
HISTORY.
FORMER FBI PROFILER TOM FUENTES,
ASSISTANT DIRECTOR OF THE FBI
AND JIM JOHNSON, CHAIRMAN OF
THE, HE'S FIRST OF ALL,
BALTIMORE COUNTY POLICE CHIEF
AND CHAIRMAN OF THE NATIONAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT PARTNERSHIP TO
PREVENT GUN VIOLENCE.
GENTLEMEN, THANKS VERY MUCH FOR
COMING IN.
CHIEF JOHNSON, LET ME START WITH
YOU.
THE NOTION OF QUICKLY GOING INTO
A SITUATION LIKE THIS RATHER
THAN STUDYING IT FROM THE
OUTSIDE.
THIS IS A RELATIVELY NEW
TACTICAL MOVE, RIGHT?
>> CERTAINLY OVER THE LAST TEN
YEARS LAW ENFORCEMENT HAS
ENTERED INTO THE ACTIVE SHOOTER
SCENARIO WHERE WE DO NOT WAIT.
WHEN WE HAVE SUFFICIENT
PERSONNEL AND EQUIPMENT AND
TOOLS, WE MAKE AN ENTRY TO
STABILIZE THE SITUATION.
>> THE OTHER VERY DISTURBING
ELEMENT IN THIS, TOM, IS THAT
WE'RE SEEING MORE OF THESE YOUNG
MEN, THEY'RE DRESSED IN MILITARY
CLOTHING, IF YOU WILL, ARMORED
VESTS.
THEY'RE DRESSED IN BLACK AND
THEY GO IN AND START KILLING
PEOPLE.
IS THERE A CONNECTION, IN YOUR
MIND, WHAT THEY CALL COPY CATS
AS FAR AS THESE MASS KILLINGS
ARE CONCERNED.
>> WE LOOK AT COPY CATS AS
SOMEBODY FOLLOWING AN EVENT.
SOMEBODY ELSE KILLED A GROUP OF
PEOPLE AND THEY'RE GOING TO DO
IT.
WHAT THEY HAVE SEEN IN MOVIES OR
VIDEO GAMES FOR MANY YEARS.
IN THOSE SITUATIONS THEY'RE
SEEING THE RAMBOS OF THE WORLD
DRESSED UP IN BATTLE GEAR AND
ASSAULT RIFLES AND SHOOTING A
LOT OF PEOPLE.
SO, IF THEY'RE TRYING TO PROVE
THEIR MANHOOD, SO TO SPEAK, IN
THEIR DILUTIONAL WORLD, THAT MAY
BE THEIR WAY TO SAY THEY'RE
STRONG AND POWERFUL AND THEY'RE
GOING TO PROVE IT TO THE WORLD
BY CARRYING ON AS IF THEY'RE IN
THE SPECIAL FORCES OPERATION OR
SOMETHING.
>> CHIEF JOHNSON, DO YOU AGREE
WITH THAT ASSESSMENT?
>> I DO.
I THINK AMERICA CAN DO A LOT
MORE ON THIS ISSUE.
THE NATIONAL PARTNERSHIP PREVENT
GUN VIOLENCE IN THIS CASE.
WE KNOW THAT OVER 40% OF ALL
GUNS ARE REQUIRED OUTSIDE OF
DEALER SALES.
WE KNOW THERE NEEDS TO BE A
LIMIT ON HIGH-CAPACITY
MAGAZINES.
I THINK AMERICA IS BECOMING MORE
AWARE AND MORE EDUCATED ABOUT
THE FACTS AND CIRCUMSTANCES THAT
HAVE LED TO THIS, FRANKLY,
NATIONAL PUBLIC HEALTH CRISIS
HERE AND THE GUN VIOLENCE WE'RE
EXPERIENCING ACROSS THIS GREAT
NATION.
>> WE EARLIER, TOM, HAD A DEBATE
HERE.
WE HEARD FROM A CONGRESSMAN WHO
WANTS TIGHTER GUN RESTRICTIONS
AND ANOTHER INDIVIDUAL SAYS THE
MORE GUNS OUT THERE, THE SAFER
ALL OF US WILL BE.
THIS DEBATE HAS BEEN GOING ON
FOR A LONG TIME.
ALL OF OUR VIEWERS KNOW FOR A
LONG TIME.
I EXPECT IT WILL INTENSIFY.
TOM, WHAT SHOULD BE DONE IN THE
SHORT TERM TO DEAL WITH THIS
PROBLEM?
>> IN THE SHORT TERM, WE NEED TO
TALK ABOUT IT.
WE NEED TO GET OUR CONGRESS TO
TALK ABOUT, THE PRESIDENT TO
PURSUE IT, STATE LEGISLATURES TO
ACTUALLY PURSUE IT AND NOT TREAT
THIS LIKE IT'S THE THIRD RAIL OF
POLITICS AND NOBODY CAN BRING IT
UP BECAUSE THEY WON'T BE
ELECTED.
FRANKLY, YOU KNOW, THE
CONGRESSMAN THAT HAVE JUST GOT
ELECTED TO THE NEXT TERM ARE
ALREADY PLANNING THEIR
RE-ELECTION FOR TWO YEARS FROM
NOW.
SO, THERE'S A FEAR AMONG THEM TO
TAKE THIS ISSUE ON AND END THEIR
POLITICAL CAREERS BY TRYING TO
TAKE ON THE POWERFUL GUN LOBBY
OR SOME OF THE MISINFORMATION
THAT HAS BEEN PRODUCED OUT THERE
ABOUT GUN SAFETY.
I KNOW THE CHIEF AGREES WITH ME.
I WAS A STREET POLICE OFFICER
FOR SIX YEARS BEFORE JOINING THE
FBI.
WHEN I WAS A 21-YEAR-OLD ROOKIE
COP, WE WERE TAUGHT YOU DON'T
FEAR THE BULLET OUT THERE THAT
HAS YOUR NAME ON IT.
YOU FEAR THE TENS OF THOUSANDS
OF BULLETS THAT ARE DRESSED TO
WHOM IT MAY CONCERN.
THAT IS WHAT WE HAD IN THESE
MASS SHOOTINGS.
WITH THE EXCEPTION OF THE
SHOOTER SHOOTING HIS OWN MOTHER,
THE REST OF THE SHOONGS, WHY
WOULD HE BE TARGETING 5 AND 6
YEAR OLDS AND AT THAT PARTICULAR
SCHOOL.
APPARENTLY, HE HAD NO CONNECTION
TO.
SO, WE'RE SEEING THIS TREMENDOUS
AMOUNT OF GUN VIOLENCE AND,
AGAIN, AS A FORMER STREET COP
AND AN AGENT FOR 30 YEARS, LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICERS FEAR GOING
TO A DOMESTIC DISTURBANCE
BECAUSE THEY KNOW PEOPLE ARE
HIGHLY EMOTIONAL, PROBABLY DRUNK
AND ARMED AT THE SAME TIME.
YOU HAVE THAT CONCERN MAKING
TRAFFIC STOPS.
SO, THE ISSUE OF OFFICER SAFETY,
COMMUNITY SAFETY AND NOW THE
SAFETY OF OUR OWN CHILDREN IS AT
STAKE AND HAS BEEN AT STAKE.
THE CHIEF IS CORRECT, THIS IS A
HEALTH ISSUE AS MUCH AS ANY
OTHER TYPE OF ISSUE.
>> VERY QUICKLY, CHIEF, GIVE US
A FINAL THOUGHT.
>> WELL, CERTAINLY, I THINK
AMERICA IS READY FOR CHANGE ON
THIS ISSUE.
LET'S ADDRESS THIS 40% OF GUN
SALES THAT ARE OUTSIDE OF THAT
LICENSE DEALER.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT
HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINES.
IF YOU CHOOSE TO OWN A GUN, IF
YOU HAVE THE RIGHT TO DO THAT,
YOU'RE A LEGAL OWNER, LOCK THE
GUNS UP.
LOCK THOSE GUNS UP.
IT'SP HAENED IN BALTIMORE
COUNTY.
THIS IS A LESSON WE HAVE
LEARNED.
LOCK THE GUNS UP.
>> CHIEF JOHNSON, THANKS VERY
MUCH.
TOM FUENTES, AS USUAL, THANKS TO
YOU, AS WELL.
>>> WE'LL TAKE A QUICK BREAK.
WHEN WE RETURN, SAYING GOOD-BYE.
AND WE CAN SAVE YOU
10% ON GROUND SHIPPING
OVER THE UPS STORE.
LOOK THIS ISN'T
MY FIRST CHRISTMAS.
THESE DEALS ALL SEEM GREAT
AT THE TIME...
BUT LATER...
[ shirt ]
MERRY CHRISTMAS, EVERYBODY!
NOT SO MUCH.
HO HO HO!
THIS ISN'T
THAT KIND OF DEAL.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SAVE ON GROUND SHIPPING
AT FEDEX OFFICE.
HOW MUCH IS
YOUR CURRENT PHONE BILL?
FOUR SIXTEEN SEVENTY SIX
A MONTH!
OKAY, COME WITH ME --
WE'RE GONNA SAVE YOU MONEY.
WITH STRAIGHT TALK
AT WALMART,
YOU GET UNLIMITED TALK,
TEXT AND DATA
FOR ONLY $45 A MONTH
PER PHONE.
WOULD WE GET
THE SAME COVERAGE?
SAME COVERAGE
ON AMERICA'S BEST NETWORKS.
YOU SAVED $146.76
BY SWITCHING TO STRAIGHT TALK.
AWESOME!
NOW YOU CAN AFFORD
TO SHARE YOUR ALLOWANCE
WITH ME.
GET THE SEASON'S
HOTTEST SMARTPHONES
LIKE THE SAMSUNG GALAXY S2
AND GET STRAIGHT TALK
WITH UNLIMITED DATA
FOR JUST $45 A MONTH --
FROM AMERICA'S
GIFT HEADQUARTERS. WALMART.
♪
>> JUST A TRAGIC, TRAGIC
SITUATION FOR THE TEACHERS, THE
PRINCIPALS AND THOSE ANGELS,
THAT'S ALL I KEEP THINKING ABOUT
ARE THOSE ANGELS.
♪
>> I MEAN, WHEN THINGS HAPPEN TO
YOUR CHILDREN AND TO OTHER
PEOPLE'S CHILDREN, I CAN'T LOOK
AT MY CHILDREN'S FACES NOW
WITHOUT SEEING THE FACES OF
EVERY ONE OF THEIR SCHOOLMATES.
♪