>> PEOPLE OF ALL AGES AND FAITHS
AND RELIGION ARE PAUSING TO
REMEMBER -- PAUSING TO REMEMBER,
REFLECT, AND GRIEVE TOGETHER.
IN THE NEXT HOUR, WE'RE GOING TO
HAVE THIS INTERFAITH SERVICE IN
THE HIGH SCHOOL JUST OVER MY
SHOULDER, WHERE SO MANY PEOPLE
WILL BE GATHERED.
HUNDREDS HAVE ALREADY LINED UP.
ALREADY THE HALL INSIDE IS
NEARLY FULL.
I CAN SEE HUNDREDS MORE STILL
LINED UP IN THE RAIN AND THE
COLD HOPING TO GET IN, HOPING TO
JUST BE TOGETHER.
WE'VE SEEN THAT SO MUCH THE LAST
DAY OR SO, PEOPLE JUST WANTING
TO BE HERE AND BE TOGETHER.
PEOPLE COME FROM ALL PARTS OF
CONNECTICUT JUST TO COME AND BE
HERE AND WITNESS WHAT'S
HAPPENING HERE AND DROP OFF SOME
FLOWERS OR A TEDDY BEAR OR A TOY
OR SOMETHING, LEAVE A
REMEMBRANCE AND PAUSE AND
REFLECT.
PEOPLE ALL AROUND THE WORLD ARE
DOING THE SAME.
I'M JOINED BY MANY OF OUR
COLLEAGUES, OUR CORRESPONDENTS
ALL THROUGHOUT THIS TOWN
COVERING THE VARIETY OF
DIFFERENT MEMORIALS THAT ARE
TAKING PLACE, AND JOINED ALSO
RIGHT NOW BY WOLF BLITZER.
WOLF, I KNOW YOU TALKED TO TWO
RELIGIOUS LEADERS ABOUT THE
SHOOTING.
I TALKED TO A NUMBER LAST NIGHT,
A RABBI AND A REVEREND.
YOU TALKED TO A LOCAL RABBI AND
A REVEREND AS WELL.
BOTH OF THEM WILL BE AT THAT
SERVICE TONIGHT.
>> YES, THEY'RE BOTH GOING TO BE
THERE TONIGHT.
THEY'RE GOING TO BE LEADING THE
SERVICE.
AND I HAD A CHANCE TO GO TO THE
CHURCH YESTERDAY AND HAD A GOOD
CONVERSATION ABOUT GOD AND HOW
THESE HORRIBLE TRAGEDIES CAN
HAPPEN IN A SITUATION LIKE THIS.
THERE ARE NO EASY ANSWERS, AND
THE CLERGY, NO MATTER HOW SMART,
NO MATTER HOW POWERFUL, NO
MATTER HOW ASTUTE CERTAINLY CAN
COMFO
COMFORT.
BOTH THE RABBI AND THE MINISTER,
THEY WERE IN THE FIREHOUSE WHEN
THE FAMILIES OF THE 20 KIDS WERE
TOLD THAT THEIR LITTLE BOY, OR
THEIR LITTLE GIRL, 6-YEAR-OLD OR
7-YEAR-OLD, HAD PASSED AWAY, HAD
DIED, HAD BEEN KILLED IN THIS
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SHOOTING.
SOME OF THE PARENTS WERE MEMBERS
OF THEIR RESPECTIVE
CONGREGATIONS, AND THEY TRIED TO
DO WHATEVER THEY COULD TO
CONSOLE.
LET ME PLAY A LITTLE EXCERPT OF
OUR CONVERSATION AT THE CHURCH
YESTERDAY.
>> SO MANY PEOPLE HAVE SAID TO
ME, REVEREND AND RABBI, HOW CAN
GOD ALLOW SOMETHING LIKE THIS TO
HAPPEN?
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
>> ONE OF THE THINGS I FIRST SAY
IN THIS MOMENT, THIS IS NOT THE
MOMENT TO ANSWER THAT QUESTION,
AT LEAST NOT TO THE FAMILIES
THAT ARE IN GRIEF.
I THINK THERE ARE ANSWERS.
THERE ARE ANSWERS FROM MY
TRADITION THAT SPEAK TO
SUFFERING AND HOW SUFFERING CAN
BE TRANSFORMATIVE, HOW AS A
CHRISTIAN, I UNDERSTAND THAT
THERE ARE WAYS IN WHICH WE CAN
TRANSFORM AND BE TRANSFORMED BY
SUFFERING.
BUT TO BE HONEST WITH YOU,
THAT'S NOT A QUESTION THAT I TRY
TO ANSWER TODAY BECAUSE PEOPLE
DON'T NEED TO HEAR WHAT BECOMES
AN OVERSIMPLISTIC ANSWER TO
SOMETHING THAT IS SO DEEP AND
PROFOUND.
>> WHAT WILL BE THE CENTRAL
MESSAGE THAT YOU TELL YOUR
CONGREGANTS TOMORROW MORNING.
>> I WILL BE PREACHING A MESSAGE
THAT, EVEN IN THE MIDST OF
DARKNESS, THERE IS LIGHT.
IT'S TRAGIC THAT WE ARE IN THE
MIDST OF THE SEASON FOR US AS
CHRISTIANS, WHICH IS
CHRISTMASTIME AND ADVENT, WHICH
IS A HOLY TIME FOR US, BUT WE
ALSO KNOW IN THE MIDST OF A
SEASON THAT WE SO OFTEN
ASSOCIATE WITH JOY AND
MERRIMENT, THAT IT'S ALSO A
SEASON OF DARKNESS.
IN FACT, THE GOSPEL OF JOHN
TELLS US THAT THE LIGHT SHINES
IN THE DARKNESS, AND THE
DARKNESS DOES NOT OVERCOME IT.
I'LL BE PREACHING A MESSAGE THAT
MS PROS, EVEN IN THE MIDST OF
THESE DARK TIMES, THAT WE KNOW
THAT THE LIGHT OF GOD IS WITH US
AND THAT WE CAN BE SUSTAINED IN
THAT AND THAT WE CAN SEE THAT
LIGHT IN EACH OTHER AND DRAW
FROM THAT LIGHT THAT IS A PART
OF OUR FAITH.
>> THE MOST IMPORTANT THING THAT
WE CAN DO AS A REACTION TO THIS
IS TO THRIVE.
I SET MY BANQUET IN THE PRESENCE
OF MY ENEMIES.
THE ENEMY IS THE HORRIBLE EVENT,
AND THE BANQUET IS CONTINUING OR
THRIVING IN LIFE.
I LIVED IN ISRAEL FOR TEN YEARS,
AND I SAW THE WAY THAT THE
ISRAELIS WOULD PICK UP AND GO
RIGHT TO THE SPOT WHERE
SOMETHING TERRIBLE HAD HAPPENED,
AND THE MESSAGE WAS WE CARRY ON,
AND WE WILL CARRY ON.
WE HAVE GREAT SCHOOLS IN
NEWTOWN.
THIS WAS AN ISOLATED INCIDENT.
THIS EVENT DOESN'T DEFINE US.
WE WILL CONTINUE TO HAVE GREAT
SCHOOLS AND BE A GREAT
COMMUNITY.
MATTHEW AND I ARE GREAT FRIENDS,
AND ALL THE CLERGY ARE GREAT
FRIENDS, AND WE WILL RECOVER.
>> RABBI PRAVER AND PASTOR
CREBBEN WILL BOTH BE AT THE
SERVICE TONIGHT WHERE MEMBERS OF
THE COMMUNITY WILL BE AT THE
PRAYER SERVICE.
WE HEARD PRESIDENT OBAMA SPENT
MOST OF THE DAY PREPARING HIS
REMARKS, SPEAKING FROM THE
HEART, SPEAKING FOR THE NATION,
BUT ALSO SPEAKING AS THE FATHER
OF TWO YOUNG DAUGHTERS AS WELL.
ALL WE CAN THINK OF NOW,
ESPECIALLY WHEN WE SEE THE
PICTURES OF THE 6 AND 7-YEAR-OLD
KIDS, THE MEMORIALS, THE
SERVICES THAT ARE CONTINUING.
BROOK BALDWIN IS JOINING US NOW
WITH DETAILS ON A FEW OF THE
VICTIMS.
BROOK, THIS IS A HEARTBREAKING
STORY FOR ALL OF US.
>> Reporter: IT IS ABSOLUTELY
GUT WRENCHING, WOLF.
WHEN YOU WALK AROUND NEWTOWN AND
SEE THE MEMORIALS AND SEE THE
ADULTS HOLDING THE HANDS OF
THEIR 4 AND 5-YEAR-OLDS CARRYING
TEDDY BEARS, WHO ARE WIPING
TEARS AWAY AS THEY PLACE THESE
TEDDY BEARS DOWN PERHAPS FOR
YOUNG PEOPLE THEY KNEW, PERHAPS
FOR YOUNG PEOPLE THEY DIDN'T,
BUT THEY WANT TO PAY RESPECT.
WE WANT TO PAY RESPECT.
AS WE TALK SO MUCH ABOUT THESE
LITTLE LIVES LOST, ALL 20 OF
THEM, IT IS SO IMPORTANT FOR US
BEFORE THIS MEMORIAL FOR US TO
TALK ABOUT THE ADULTS, AND
REALLY THE HEROES AT THE SCHOOL.
I WANT TO BEGIN BY TALKING ABOUT
VICTORIA, VICKI SOTO.
SHE WAS YOUNG HERSELF, FIRST
GRADE TEACHER, 27 YEARS OF AGE.
SHE HEARD THE GUNSHOTS AND
IMMEDIATELY GRABBED HER STUDENTS
AND TRIED TO MOVE THEM AWAY,
MOVE THEM AWAY FROM THE DOOR
WHEN HE ENTERED THE SCHOOL.
SHE IS ACTUALLY BELIEVED TO HAVE
HAD THE FORESIGHT TO HAVE HIDDEN
SOME OF HER STUDENTS INSIDE A
CLOSET IN THE FIRST GRADE
CLASSROOM, AND LATER POLICE
FOUND SEVEN OF THEM, SEVEN
SURVIVORS, THANKS TO VICKI SOTO
INSIDE THAT CLOSET.
LET ME READ THIS QUOTE FROM HER
COUSIN.
"SHE INSTINCTIVELY WENT INTO
ACTION WHEN A MONSTER CAME INTO
THE CLASSROOM AND TRIED TO
PROTECT THE KIDS SHE LOVED SO
MUCH.
WE WANT THE PUBLIC TO KNOW THAT
VICKI WAS A HERO."
TWO OTHER PEOPLE FROM THE
SCHOOL, YOU NEED TO HEAR THEIR
STORIES.
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, THE PRINCIPAL,
47 YEARS OF AGE.
SHE'D BEEN AT THE SCHOOL FOR TWO
YEARS.
WHEN YOU TALK TO PEOPLE WHO KNEW
HER, A FRIEND SAID SHE'S
PASSIONATE.
SHE ALWAYS HAD A SMILE ON HER
FACE.
SHE WAS JUST THAT KIND OF
EDUCATOR YOU WANTED IN CHARGE OF
YOUR STUDENTS.
KIDS LOVED HER.
THE FRIEND THAT WENT ON TO SAY
SHE WAS A TOUGH WOMAN BUT IN THE
RIGHT SENSE TOUGH.
AS I MENTIONED, SHE WAS A NEWER
PRINCIPAL, AND ONE OF HER
PRIORITIES, WHICH SHE, IN FACT,
FOLLOWED THROUGH ON, WAS
INSTALLING THIS NEW SECURITY
SYSTEM AT THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
SO THAT, IF THERE WERE TO BE A
STRANGER OR VISITOR TO COME TO
THE SCHOOL AFTER THE SCHOOL
DOORS CLOSED AT 9:30 IN THE
MORNING, THEY WOULD HAVE TO RING
THE BELL.
SECURITY VERY IMPORTANT FOR DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG.
FRIDAY MORNING, SHE WAS IN A
MEETING, ACCORDING TO A PARENT,
WITH THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST,
AND THEY HEARD THE POP, POP,
POP, AND IMMEDIATELY SPRANG INTO
ACTION.
AND LUNGED FOR THE SHOOTER, AND
THAT IS WHEN SHE PASSED AWAY.
ONE REPORT, AS SHE WAS LUNGING
FOR THIS YOUNG MAN, THERE WAS A
TEACHER DOWN THE HALLWAY, WHO
SHE YELLED AT, GET IN THE
CLASSROOM, CLOSE THE DOOR, LOCK
THE DOOR FROM THE INSIDE, ALL OF
THIS FROM THIS PRINCIPAL LUNGING
AT THE SHOOTER.
SHE WAS MARRIED.
SHE HAD TWO DAUGHTERS, THREE
STEPDAUGHTERS.
LET ME READ YOU THIS ONE TWEET,
WOLF.
THIS WAS FROM HER 30-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHTER, CHRISTINE.
"MY MOM WAS TAKEN TRAGICALLY
FROM ME, BUT SHE WENT DOWN IN A
BLAZE OF GLORY THAT TRULY
REPRESENTS WHO SHE WAS."
JUST TWO OF THE MANY NAMES,
WOLF, WE'RE FINALLY HEARING A
LITTLE BIT MORE, THE STORIES,
HOW THEY WANT TO BE REMEMBERED
IN THIS TRAGIC, TRAGIC TIME IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> WE'RE ONLY BEGINNING TO LEARN
ABOUT SOME OF THE OTHER VICTIMS
OF THIS TRAGEDY AS WELL, BROOK.
THANKS VERY MUCH.
SO MANY PEOPLE HAVE COME UP TO
ME ON THE STREETS HERE IN
NEWTOWN OVER THE PAST DAY OR TWO
AND SAID THEY WOULD LIKE TO DO
SOMETHING TO HELP.
FOR THOSE OF YOU WHO WOULD LIKE
TO HELP THOSE AFFECTED, HERE'S
WHAT YOU CAN DO.
YOU CAN GO TO CNN.COM/IMPACT.
YOU CAN IMPACT YOUR WORLD.
WE'VE GOT GOOD IDEAS WHAT YOU
CAN DO RIGHT HERE IN NEWTOWN AND
THE AREA.
SOME GOOD IDEAS AT
CNN.COM/IMPACT.
ANDERSON?
>> THANKS VERY MUCH.
YOU JUST HEARD BROOK BALDWIN
TALK ABOUT DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, THE
PRINCIPAL OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY, A LONGTIME EDUCATOR.
SHE'D BEEN AT THE SCHOOL, I
THINK, FOR 12 YEARS.
WE'VE BEEN HEARING SO MUCH ABOUT
HER JUST IN THE LAST COUPLE OF
DAYS.
THERE'S SO MANY OTHER PEOPLE
THAT WE' REALLY JUST STARTING
TO LEARN ABOUT.
DAWN BECAME THE PRINCIPAL OF
SANDY HOOK TWO YEARS AGO.
LILIAN IS THE FORMER CHAIR OF
THE NEWTOWN BOARD OF EDUCATION.
SHE HELPED CHOOSE DAWN FOR THAT
POSITION.
SHE JOINS ME NOW.
LILIAN, YOU KNEW ALL OF THE
EDUCATORS WHO WERE KILLED.
YOU KNEW A NUMBER OF THE
CHILDREN AS WELL.
FIRST OF ALL, HOW ARE YOU
HOLDING UP?
>> MY FAMILIES, IT COMES AND
GOES.
THE FIRST DAY WE WERE A MESS AND
COULDN'T SLEEP AT NIGHT.
JUST LIKE EVERYBODY ELSE IN
NEWTOWN, I COULDN'T SLEEP.
AT 3:00 IN THE MORNING, I GOT
UP, POWERED UP MY COMPUTER, AND
HALF OF NEWTOWN WAS ON FACEBOOK.
YOU DO WHAT YOU CAN.
I JUST TOOK A MEAL TO ONE OF THE
FAMILIES.
EVERYONE'S DOING THAT.
THE GROCERY STORE WAS -- THE NAR
WHERE THE DISHES ARE THAT YOU
BUY TO GIVE IS DECIMATED.
SO EVERYONE'S TRYING TO HELP
NOW.
>> WHAT DO YOU WANT PEOPLE TO
KNOW ABOUT THIS PLACE, ABOUT
THIS SCHOOL?
>> I WAS INVOLVED WITH SANDY
HOOK FOR 17 YEARS WITH MY
CHILDREN AND WITH A PROGRAM I
RUN THERE, AND THIS SCHOOL IS
UNIQUE IN THE FACT THAT, FOR
INSTANCE, THE PARENT COMMUNITY
IS SO STRONG.
THERE WAS NEVER A TIME WE HAD TO
BEG FOR VOLUNTEERS.
WE HAD SOMETIMES TO TURN
VOLUNTEERS AWAY BECAUSE IT WAS
SUCH AN ENGAGED COMMUNITY.
THE STAFF, THE TEACHERS --
EVERYONE SAYS, WELL, TEACHERS
LOVE THEIR CHILDREN, AND THAT'S
VERY TRUE, BUT IN SANDY HOOK YOU
NEVER DOUBTED THAT THIS STAFF
WAS COMMITTED TO EVERY CHILD, NO
MATTER THEIR ABILITY RATE, AND
THAT THEY WERE VERY FOCUSED ON
MAKING SURE THAT EVERY CHILD
SUCCEEDED.
OUR MOTTO AT SANDY HOOK WAS ALL
CHILDREN CAN AND WILL LEARN
WELL, AND THE TEACHERS TOOK THAT
VERY SERIOUSLY.
SO FOR ME AS A PARENT AND AS
SOMEONE WHO WORKED IN THE SCHOOL
AS A REGULAR VOLUNTEER, IT WAS A
PLACE OF JOY AND LOVE.
AND TO IMAGINE THOSE LITTLE
CHILDREN HAVING THAT VIOLATED IN
ALL OF US, THIS RIPPLES OUT
BEYOND WHO'S IN THE SCHOOL
TODAY.
THE COLLEGE KIDS THAT USED TO GO
TO SANDY HOOK, THEY'RE
DEVASTATED.
THEY'RE OUT THERE TALKING,
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHAT TO DO
NEXT.
THEY'RE BECOMING ACTIVISTS IN
DIFFERENT AREAS.
FOR THIS TO HAPPEN TO THIS
SCHOOL THAT WAS SO CONNECTED
THROUGH THE YEARS, NOT JUST
WHO'S THERE TODAY, BUT WE ALL
FEEL SO CONNECTED, IT MAKES IT
MUCH MORE TRAGIC AND MUCH MORE
VIOLATED.
>> I ALWAYS THINK TEACHERS ARE
HEROES ON ANY GIVEN DAY.
>> YES, I AGREE.
>> BUT WHAT HAPPENED ON THAT
DAY, I TALKED TO ONE TEACHER
WHO, WHEN SHE SENSED SOMETHING
WAS GOING ON BUT DIDN'T KNOW
WHAT, GATHERED HER KIDS, SAT
THEM DOWN IN THE CORNER AS THEY
DRILLED, AND READ TO THEM.
>> WAS THAT MRS. FULNER?
>> RIGHT.
CONTINUED TO READ TO THEM.
>> CONSUMMATE PROFESSIONALS
ALWAYS HAVE THE CHILDREN
FOREMOST IN THEIR MIND, WHICH IS
TRUE FOR TEACHERS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY, AND I KNOW THAT.
BUT IN FOLLOWING THE DRILLS,
MAKING SURE ALL THE DRILLS WE'D
DONE, THEY ALL FOLLOWED THOSE
PROCEDURES.
WHOEVER IN THE OFFICE, ONE OF
THE SECRETARIES, LEFT THAT
INTERCOM ON, THAT'S ONE OF THE
BIGGEST HEROES OF THIS NIGHT.
>> THAT'S HOW EVERYONE KNEW
SOMETHING WAS GOING ON.
>> THAT'S WHAT I MEAN ABOUT THIS
COMMUNITY.
WHERE WE GO FROM HERE IS WE HAVE
TO LEAD WITH LOVE, AND THAT'S
WHAT I'M CONCERNED ABOUT, THAT
IN THE SHORT TERM, LEADING WITH
LOVE TO PUT OUR ARMS AROUND THE
FAMILIES.
EVERYONE ACROSS THE WORLD IS
ASKING, HOW DO WE HELP?
YOU HELP WITH LOVE.
THEN YOU DON'T LET LITTLE 6 AND
7-YEAR-OLD KIDS GET TRAPPED IN
THEIR CLASSROOMS AND GUNNED DOWN
BY A MAD MAN WITH NO WAY OUT AND
NOT HAVE THAT CHANGE THE WAY WE
RESPOND TO THIS KIND OF
VIOLENCE.
WE HAVE TO GO FORWARD.
>> SOMETHING HAS TO CHANGE.
I DON'T HAVE THE ANSWERS.
BUT I THINK WE'VE GOT TO HAVE A
PEACEFUL, LOVING DISCUSSION AS A
COUNTRY AND MAYBE AT THE WORLD
LEVEL ABOUT MULTIPLE ISSUES,
INCLUDING MENTAL HEALTH, GUN
CONTROL, AND HOW WE BUILD OUR
SCHOOLS.
SANDY HOOK HAD THAT INTERCOM IN
PLACE AFTER COLUMBINE.
YOU COULD NOT GET INTO THAT
SCHOOL.
HE SHOT HIS WAY IN THROUGH GLASS
DOORS.
PERHAPS THE SCHOOLS NEED TO BE
CHANGED, BUT WE STRUCTURE
MATERIALS.
AND I KNOW, BEING A BOARD
MEMBER, EVERYTHING IS MONEY.
SO WE HAVE TO LOOK AT THIS.
WHAT I WANT IS EVERYONE TO COME
AT THIS IN A LOVING WAY.
WE'RE SO DIVISIVE ANY WAY AS A
COUNTRY, BUT THIS SHOULD BE A
DEFINING MOMENT WHERE WE COME
TOGETHER AND SOLVE THIS PROBLEM
TOGETHER.
>> I'VE HAD SO MANY PEOPLE COME
UP AND TAKE ME BY THE HAND OR
THE ARM AND SAY SOMETHING'S GOT
TO COME OUT OF THIS.
>> YOU CAN'T LET LITTLE
CHILDREN -- ALL THE OTHER
TRAGEDIES WE'VE HAD HAVE BEEN
HORRIFIC, AND NOW WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT BABIES.
AND GUNNED DOWN WITH A WEAPON
THAT DIDN'T TAKE ANY
MARKSMANSHIP AT ALL.
IT'S UNCONSCIONABLE THIS STILL
HAPPENS IN THIS COUNTRY AND THIS
PLACE OF PEACE AND LOVE AND JOY
WHERE EVERYONE FELT SAFE, I HAD
TO SMILE.
I WAS MUCH WAING WHAT YOU GUYS
WERE DOING NOW.
EVERY TIME YOU SAY SANDY HOOK,
WHAT IT RESONATES IN ME IS
CHILDHOOD BECAUSE OF SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL, AND THAT'S AN INNOCENCE,
AND IT'S GONE NOW.
WE'LL GET IT BACK.
THIS COMMUNITY WILL GET IT BACK.
>> A LOT OF PEOPLE HAVE SAID
THAT IN NEWTOWN, A COUPLE OF
PEOPLE CAME UP TO ME LAST NIGHT
AND SAID, LOOK, THIS IS NOT WHO
WE ARE.
WE WANT THIS TOWN TO BE KNOWN
FOR WHO WE ARE.
>> AND THAT'S LOVE, AND THE
CARING AND COMPASSION.
>> AND WE SEE THAT IN THE
MEMORIALS THAT HAVE SPRUNG UP
EVERYWHERE.
>> IT'S MORE THAN PEOPLE SHOWING
UP.
IT'S PEOPLE REALLY, TRULY
BONDING, WHENEVER A FAMILY HAS A
TRAGEDY, BONDING AROUND THAT
FAMILY, 9/11, ANYTHING THAT'S
HAPPENED IN NEWTOWN, PEOPLE RISE
TO THE OCCASION.
THAT'S WONDERFUL FOR US THAT'S
HERE, BUT WE CAN'T HAVE THIS
KEEP HAPPENING IN THE FUTURE OR
EVEN IN ANOTHER NEWTOWN SCHOOL.
I MEAN, WHO KNOWS?
>> I APPRECIATE YOU BEING WITH
US.
>> THANK YOU, ANDERSON.
>> AND, WOLF, WE'VE HEARD THAT
FROM SO MANY PEOPLE, WANT
SOMETHING TO COME OUT OF THIS,
WANT SOMETHING TO BE DONE.
MAYBE WE'LL HEAR MORE ABOUT IT
TONIGHT AT THIS SERVICE WE'LL BE
STARTING AROUND 7:00.
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, ALREADY
THIS EVENING.
OBVIOUSLY, WOLF, HE'LL BE
ATTENDING THAT SERVICE AND
SPEAKING AT THAT SERVICE.
>> THE FOLKS ARE ARRIVING AT THE
AUDITORIUM, AT THE HIGH SCHOOL,
NOT VERY FAR FROM YOU ARE, RIGHT
DOWN THE STREET FROM WHERE I AM
IN NEWTOWN.
YOU SEE SOME OF THE DIGNITARIES.
IF YOU LOOK ON THE RIGHT SIDE OF
YOUR SCREEN, YOU CAN SEE NEAR
THE STAGE SENATOR JOE LIEBERMAN
STANDING THERE.
THIS IS A DIFFERENT SHOT.
SENATOR LIEBERMAN, SENATOR
BLUMENTHAL, THE OTHER SENATOR
FROM CONNECTICUT, SENATOR
MURPHY, THE INCOMING SENATOR,
AND YOU SEE CLERGY THAT HAVE
GATHERED TO PARTICIPATE IN THIS
INTERFAITH SERVICE.
THERE'S SENATOR LIEBERMAN IN THE
RIGHT CORNER OF YOUR SCREEN.
PEOPLE HAVE COME FROM ALL OVER
THIS STATE.
THEY WANT TO BE PART OF THIS.
THEY WANT TO BE A PART OF THIS
MEMORIAL SERVICE, AND PEOPLE ARE
JUST COMING HERE TO NEWTOWN TO
DO WHATEVER THEY CAN.
DONE LEMON IS OUT IN THE STREETS
WATCHING WHAT'S GOING ON.
DON, IT STARTED VERY SLOWLY,
WHAT WE SAW, PEOPLE JUST
BRINGING SOME TOYS OR SOME
FLOWERS, A CHRISTMAS TREE,
LEGOS.
YOU'VE BEEN SHOWING IT TO OUR
VIEWERS.
NOW IT'S GROWING, AS YOU SAY,
VERY, VERY QUICKLY.
PEOPLE WANT TO SHOW THEIR
RESPECT.
>> Reporter: YEAH, THEY DO.
I SAID EXPONENTIALLY, AND IT IS
GROWING EXPONENTIALLY.
NOT JUST FROM AROUND THE STATE,
BUT FROM ALL OVER THE AREA,
TRISTATE AREA AND BEYOND.
I WANT OUR VIEWERS TO SEE THIS.
YOU SEE THE PICTURES THERE OF
TWO LITTLE CHERUBS.
YOU SEE THE STUFFED ANIMALS,
DOGS, WINNIE THE POOH AND
FLOWERS PEOPLE HAVE BEEN BUYING.
EVERY SECOND SOMEONE DROPS
SOMETHING OFF.
CANDY CANES HERE AND ORNAMENTS
ON THE CHRISTMAS TREES.
LET ME INTRODUCE YOU TO SOME OF
THESE PEOPLE.
WE'RE GOING TO WALK THROUGH AND
TALK.
IF THEY DON'T WANT TO TALK TO
US, WE'LL BE VERY RESPECTFUL.
YOU'RE FROM NEW YORK, ROMAN?
YOU CAME ALL THE WAY FROM NEW
YORK WHY?
>> BECAUSE I WANT TO PAY RESPECT
TO THE VICTIMS OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, AND IT'S VERY
TRAGIC.
I THINK IT'S RESPECTFUL TO COME
AND PAY RESPECT TO THE VICTIMS.
>> Reporter: YOU'RE FROM NEW
YORK.
AGAIN, NOT EVEN FROM HERE.
AS WE'VE BEEN SAYING, COMING
FROM ALL OVER.
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN WATCHING IT ON
TELEVISION, AND RATHER THAN JUST
WATCHING, YOU WANT TO BE A PART
OF IT.
YOU'RE FROM THIS TOWN, THOUGH?
>> I'M FROM SOUTHBURY, THE NEXT
TOWN OVER.
>> Reporter: IT'S VERY ODD.
YOU MEET PEOPLE FROM ALL OVER.
YOU'RE FROM MY HOMETOWN, BATON
ROUGE.
YOU AND ANDERSON HAVE BEEN
TALKING ABOUT PEOPLE COMING UP
AND TALKING TO US AND SAYING
THANK YOU FOR RESPECTFUL
COVERAGE.
THANK YOU FOR BEING HERE AND
SHOWING THE WORLD WHAT KIND OF
TOWN WE ARE, WHAT KIND OF STATE
CONNECTICUT IS.
YOU GUYS ARE REALLY BANNING
TOGETHER TO HELP THE PEOPLE
HERE.
>> THAT'S CORRECT, DON.
I'M OUT HERE TONIGHT JUST TO
SHOW PEOPLE HOW MUCH WE
APPRECIATE THEM COMING OUT,
PRAYING FOR US, LOVING US THE
WAY THEY'VE BEEN DOING OVER THE
LAST COUPLE OF DAYS.
IT'S BEEN AMAZING.
>> Reporter: I WANT TO SHOW YOU
GUYS WHERE WE ARE.
THIS IS SHOPS.
IT'S THE CENTER OF TOWN.
IT'S THE TOWN SQUARE.
USUALLY PEOPLE COME OUT HERE
DURING THE EVENINGS OR DURING
THE DAY AND SHOP OR COME TO THE
RESTAURANTS, BUT IT'S NEVER,
EVER THIS BUSY.
I JUST WANT TO WALK THROUGH TO
SHOW YOU THE CROWD OF PEOPLE WHO
HAVE GATHERED HERE.
RIGHT ACROSS THE STREET, YOU SEE
A BIG SIGN THAT SAYS GOD BLESS
SANDY HOOK.
AND IT'S FAITH, HOPE, AND LOVE,
AND LIGHTED CHRISTMAS LIGHTS
OVER THERE.
THAT'S THE STREET THAT LEADS UP
TO THE SCHOOL.
IT'S BEEN BLOCKED OFF BY POLICE
OFFICERS.
POLICE OFFICERS AND SAFETY
OFFICERS OUT HERE TO MAKE SURE
PEOPLE ARE SAFE ONCE THEY'RE OUT
HERE.
THERE WAS A FAMILY HERE, EMMITT
AND HIS FAMILY, THEY DROPPED OFF
STUFFED ANIMALS JUST TO ADD TO
THE PILE HERE.
I JUST WANT BELIEVE HOW MANY
STUFFED ANIMALS, HOW MANY PEOPLE
HAVE COME OUT AND JUST DROPPED
THINGS OFF.
THERE'S EMMITT.
EMMITT, COME TALK TO US.
YOU'RE FROM WHERE?
>> WE'RE FROM MONROE.
>> Reporter: THE NEXT TOWN OVER?
>> YES.
>> Reporter: WHICH IS BELIEVED
TO BE WHERE THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL THE KIDS ARE GOING TO GO
TO MONROE.
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
MY SON HERE RYAN ATTENDED THAT
SCHOOL.
THAT'S MY UNDERSTANDING IS
THAT'S WHERE THEY'RE GOING TO
BE.
>> Reporter: AND THIS IS YOUR
WIFE?
>> YES, JILL.
>> Reporter: YOU'RE OUT HERE
BECAUSE?
>> TO LEAVE SOME STUFFED ANIMALS
THAT ARE OUR DAUGHTERS, JUST TO
LET EVERYBODY KNOW WE'RE
THINKING OF THEM, AND OUR HEARTS
ARE WITH THEM.
>> Reporter: RYAN, YOU ATTEND
SCHOOL IN THE AREA?
>> YEAH.
>> Reporter: HOW OLD ARE YOU?
>> I'M 14.
>> Reporter: YOU'RE 14 YEARS
OLD.
YOU CAN'T IMAGINE, I'M SURE, THE
HORRIFIC EVENT THAT THESE PEOPLE
SUFFERED THROUGH AND THE KIDS
HERE.
>> YEAH, IT WAS PRETTY SHOCKING.
I WAS HOME SICK THAT FRIDAY WHEN
IT HAPPENED, AND I WOKE UP, AND
MY DAD WAS LIKE THERE WAS A
SHOOTING, AND IT WAS JUST VERY
SCARY.
I DIDN'T KNOW.
MY FRIENDS WERE TEXTING ME
SAYING, THEY'RE IN A LOCKDOWN
AND EVERYTHING.
MY MOM WAS AT THE HIGH SCHOOL
HELPING AT A BLOOD DRIVE, AND
THEY WERE JUST IN A LOCKDOWN AND
EVERYTHING.
>> Reporter: I WOULD IMAGINE
THAT YOU CAN'T -- IT'S
UNFATHOMABLE TO THINK ABOUT YOUR
SCHOOL DISTRICT, THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT THAT NEIGHBORS YOURS.
YOU FEEL SAFE AT SCHOOL USUALLY,
DON'T YOU?
>> YEAH, SOMETIMES, BUT YOU
NEVER ARE REALLY SAFE.
>> Reporter: THAT'S THE
SENTIMENT HERE.
USUALLY KIDS TAKE THEIR STUFFED
ANIMALS, AND THEY KEEP THEM
FOREVER AND PARENTS BECAUSE THEY
MEAN SOMETHING, BUT YOU WANT TO
GIVE THIS TO THESE KIDS.
>> OUR DAUGHTER IS THE SAME AGE
AS SO MANY OF THESE VICTIMS.
THIS IS A TRIBUTE TO THOSE
CHILDREN, THOSE YOUNG LIVES THAT
WERE LOST.
YOU CAN'T PUT IT INTO WORDS.
A LOT OF PEOPLE HAVE SAID THAT,
BUT YOU REALLY, TRULY CAN'T PUT
IT INTO WORDS.
>> Reporter: I IMAGINE YOU'RE
HERE BECAUSE EVERYONE IS SAYING,
WE FEEL HELPLESS IN SOME WAY.
WE WANT TO CONTRIBUTE.
>> YOU DO.
YOU FEEL ABSOLUTELY HELPLESS AND
SPEECHLESS AND JUST FEEL NUMB,
ABSOLUTELY NUMB.
>> Reporter: WOLF, THERE YOU
HAVE IT.
JUST A FEW OF THE FOLKS WHO ARE
OUT HERE.
LITERALLY HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE, IF
NOT THOUSANDS, HAVE BEEN
STREAMING THROUGH THIS MAKESHIFT
MEMORIAL.
AS WE CLOSE, I JUST WANT TO SHOW
YOU.
IT'S REALLY A BEAUTIFUL SIGHT TO
SEE IN SUCH A TRAGIC EVENT, THE
OUTPOURING AND THAT PEOPLE CARE
SO MUCH THAT THEY WOULD GIVE
SUCH PERSONAL THINGS LIKE THE
TEDDY BEARS AND THE THINGS THAT
MEAN SO MUCH TO THEM GROWING UP,
THAT THEY WOULD GIVE IT TO
SOMEONE ELSE JUST TO SHOW HOW
MUCH THEY CARE AND HOW MUCH THEY
SUPPORT THE VICTIMS AND THE
FAMILIES AND EVERYONE AROUND
THIS AREA.
>> DON, VERY, VERY MOVING.
A VERY, VERY MOVING TRIBUTE,
VERY, VERY MOVING MEMORIALS.
VERY SIMPLE, BUT VERY POWERFUL.
ONCE AGAIN, WE'RE STANDING BY TO
HEAR FROM THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES.
WE'RE TOLD RIGHT NOW THAT THE
PRESIDENT, SANJAY, HE'S STARTED
MEETING WITH FAMILIES.
HE'S COME HERE TO CONVEY HIS
CONDOLENCES TO MANY FA LIZ.
HE'S BEEN MEETING WITH SOME OF
THE FIRST RESPONDERS, AND HE'LL
BE HEADING OVER TO THE NEWTOWN
HIGH SCHOOL FAIRLY SOON FOR THE
START OF THIS INTERFAITH
MEMORIAL SERVICE.
YOU CAN SEE THE MINISTERS, THE
RABBIS, THE CLERGY, THEY'RE
GETTING READY RIGHT THERE.
THERE ON THE LEFT, YOU SEE THE
REVEREND MATTHEW CREBBEN, WHO WE
SPOKE TO EARLIER.
ON THE RIGHT, YOU SEE THE RABBI
PRAVER AS WELL.
THEY'RE GOING TO BE
PARTICIPATING IN THIS.
ALL THE FAITHS WILL BE PART OF
THIS.
SANJAY, YOU'VE STUDIED, AS A
PHYSICIAN, HOW PEOPLE GRIEVE AND
THE EMOTIONAL AND PHYSICAL
PROBLEMS THAT CAN DEVELOP.
WHEN I SPOKE TO THE RABBI AND
THE MINISTER YESTERDAY, THEY
WERE IN THE FIRE THERE IS HOUSE
WHEN THE PARENTS WERE TOLD THEIR
CHILDREN ARE DEAD, AND THEY
STARTED WAILING AND SCREAMING.
YOU CAN ONLY IMAGINE.
WHAT DO YOU DO?
THESE PEOPLE ARE STILL GOING
THROUGH THIS.
>> AND THEY WILL GO THROUGH IT
FOR A LONG TIME.
IMAGINE THE IDEA OF A PARENT
LOSING THEIR CHILD.
PERHAPS IN THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
IT'S SOMETHING THEY WON'T GET
OVER.
IT'S JUST HARD TO EVEN FATHOM,
WOLF.
I WILL TELL YOU THERE'S
DIFFERENT STAGES OF GRIEF.
THE DISBELIEF, I THINK, THAT
YOU'RE DESCRIBING IS VERY
NORMAL.
FIRST STAGE.
SOMETIMES THERE'S ANGER, AND
THAT ANGER AND SHOCK SORT OF
TOGETHER.
BUT EVENTUALLY I'M JUST SO
STRUCK BY ROBBIE PARKER'S
COMMENTS YESTERDAY --
>> THE 30-YEAR-OLD FATHER, A
PHYSICIAN'S ASSISTANT.
>> AND HIS DAUGHTER EMILIE WAS
ONE OF THE VICTIMS HERE.
HIS ACCEPTANCE AND HIS
FORGIVENESS SO SOON AFTER IS
REMARKABLE TO SEE.
I THINK THAT'S A STAGE THAT
EVENTUALLY PEOPLE GET TO, THIS
IDEA OF ACCEPTANCE.
IT DOES NOT COME EASILY, AND FOR
SOME PEOPLE IT MAY NOT COME AT
ALL, BUT THOSE ARE SORT OF THE
STAGES, I THINK.
WE TALK ABOUT IT IN A MEDICAL
SENSE, WHEN SOMEONE IS SICK IN A
HOSPITAL, FOR EXAMPLE, OR IF
YOU'VE LOST A LOVED ONE IN A
HOSPITAL, BUT CERTAINLY IN A
MASS TRAGEDY LIKE THIS, IT'S A
LOT OF THE SAME THING.
AGAIN, WE'VE TALKED ABOUT THIS
IDEA -- AND DON MENTIONED THIS
IDEA, PEOPLE SORT OF KNOWING
THAT OTHER PEOPLE ARE GOING
THROUGH THE SAME THING, THAT
THEY ARE NOT SPECIFICALLY SORT
OF EXPERIENCING THIS TOGETHER, I
THINK, CAN MAKE A HUGE
DIFFERENCE FOR THEM.
>> I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO SAY.
OUR COVERAGE WILL CONTINUE RIGHT
AFTER THIS.
THE INTERFAITH MEMORIAL SERVICE
WILL START WITH THE PRESIDENT
AND THE CLERGY AND THE FAMILIES,
THE FRIENDS, THE PEOPLE OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, AT THE
HIGH SCHOOL RIGHT AT THE TOP OF
THE HOUR.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
THIS IS AMERICA.
WE DON'T LET FREQUENT HEARTBURN
COME BETWEEN US
AND WHAT WE LOVE.
SO IF YOU'RE ONE OF THEM PEOPLE
WHO GETS HEARTBURN
AND THEN TREATS DAY AFTER DAY...
BLOCK THE ACID WITH PRILOSEC OTC
AND DON'T GET HEARTBURN
IN THE FIRST PLACE!
[ Male Announcer ]
ONE PILL EACH MORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBURN.
>>> WELCOME BACK.
I'M STANDING OUTSIDE THE HIGH
SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
WHERE PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL BE
SPEAKING.
ALONG WITH MANY CHURCH LEADERS.
AN INTERFAITH SERVICE, RABBIS,
MINISTERS FROM OTHER RELIGIONS
AS WELL.
YOU CAN SEE HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE
HAVE ALREADY GATHERED IN THE
HIGH SCHOOL.
LOOKS LIKE HUNDREDS MORE ARE
STILL IN THE LINE OUTSIDE.
MORE PEOPLE KEEP COMING.
EVERYONE JUST WANTS TO BE HERE,
WANTS TO BE PART OF THIS AND
SHARE IN THE GRIEF TOGETHER.
JASON CARROLL IS JOINING US NOW.
JASON, YOU ACTUALLY TALKED WITH
A CHURCH TEACHER WHO SPENT TIME
WITH SOME OF THE KIDS WHO WERE
AT THE SCHOOL.
HOW ARE THEY DOING?
HER NAME, ANDERSON, IS SUE
VOGELMAN.
SHE HAS VERY STRONG TIES TO
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
SHE TAUGHT THERE FOR TEN YEARS.
SHE IS NOW A CHURCH TEACHER, AND
MANY OF THE STUDENTS FROM SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY WERE IN HER
CLASSROOM TODAY.
THIS IS THE FIRST TIME THAT SO
MANY OF THE STUDENTS WERE IN A
CLASSROOM SETTING SINCE THE
TRAGIC EVENTS ON FRIDAY.
WE TALKED ABOUT HOW IT WAS FOR
HER, HOW IT WAS FOR THE
STUDENTS.
SHE SAID THERE WAS A LOT OF
ANXIETY, ANXIETY ON THE PART OF
THE PARENTS.
SOME OF THE PARENTS WERE UNSURE
ABOUT PUTTING THEIR CHILDREN
BACK IN A CLASSROOM SETTING EVEN
IF IT IS A SUNDAY SCHOOL
CLASSROOM SETTING SO SOON.
SOME OF THE CHILDREN ARE AT MUCH
DIFFERENT LEVELS.
SOME OF THE CHILDREN DIDN'T KNOW
ANYTHING ABOUT THE EVENT.
SOME OF THE CHILDREN DID KNOW.
SOME OF THE CHILDREN KNEW SOME
OF THE YOUNG BOYS AND YOUNG
GIRLS THAT HAD BEEN KILLED.
SO WE TALKED ABOUT ALL OF THOSE
THINGS IN A VERY CANDID, VERY
EMOTIONAL CONVERSATION JUST A
LITTLE EARLIER.
I WANT YOU TO LISTEN TO JUST A
SMALL SAMPLE OF THAT
CONVERSATION.
SUNDAYY SCHOOL WAS TODAY.
YOU HAD A LOT OF CHILDREN HERE
IN THIS ROOM.
WHAT WAS THAT LIKE FOR YOU?
>> THERE WAS A LITTLE BIT -- IT
WAS ACTUALLY VERY SCARY BECAUSE
I SPENT YESTERDAY TRYING TO
PREPARE FOR TODAY, BUT YOU DON'T
KNOW WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN.
AND THEN LATER ON WHERE WE GOT
TO THE PART WHERE WE PRAYED,
PRETTY MUCH EVERY CHILD IN HERE
ALL HAD A PRAYER, AND MANY OF
THEM WERE MY FRIEND JACK DIED.
MY FRIEND BEN DIED.
MY FRIEND CHARLOTTE DIED.
SO WE PRAYED.
WE PRAYED.
WE PROBABLY PRAYED MORE THAN
WE'VE EVER PRAYED BEFORE.
AND THEN SOME OF THEM PRAYED FOR
THEIR MOM AND DAD, AND SOME OF
THEM PRAYED FOR BUTTERFLIES
BECAUSE THEY'RE ALL AT DIFFERENT
PLACES.
>> AGAIN, JUST A SMALL SAMPLING
OF SOME OF THE CONVERSATION WE
WERE HAVING.
I'LL SHOW THAT LATER TONIGHT ON
YOUR SHOW, ANDERSON.
ONE OF THE OTHER POINTS SHE
WANTED TO MAKE ABOUT WHAT WAS
HAPPENING WITH HER TODAY IS THAT
SHE REALLY FELT STRONGLY THAT
WHAT IS HELPING HER, SOME OF THE
OTHER TEACHERS, AND EVEN SOME OF
THE CHILDREN GET THROUGH ALL OF
THIS IS THE FACT THAT THEY'VE
BEEN RECEIVING AN OUTPOURING OF
SUPPORT FROM ALL OVER THE
COUNTRY.
AND STRANGELY ENOUGH, EVEN SOME
OF THE YOUNG CHILDREN ARE
FEELING THAT.
SOME OF THE CHILDREN THAT KNEW
ABOUT WHAT HAD HAPPENED SAID
THEY KNEW THEY WERE GETTING
WORDS OF ENCOURAGEMENT FROM AS
FAR AWAY PLACES AS SOUTH AMERICA
AND SOUTH AFRICA.
SO THOSE WERE SOME OF THE
POSITIVE THINGS THAT HAPPENED,
BUT THERE WAS A LOT OF EMOTION
THERE IN THAT CLASSROOM TODAY.
ANDERSON?
>> THERE'S EMOTION REALLY
EVERYWHERE IN THIS TOWN.
I'VE HAD PEOPLE COME UP TO ME
AND SAY, I HAVE NO MORE TEARS
LEFT.
AND YET WE SEE PEOPLE CRYING ALL
THE TIME.
IT'S HARD NOT TO WHEN YOU'RE
HERE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S ARRIVAL, OF
COURSE, REMINDS US OF THE MANY
DIFFICULT ROLES THAT A PRESIDENT
PLAYS IN OUR NATIONAL LIFE.
I WANT TO BRING IN OUR CHIEF
WHITE HOUSE CORRESPONDENT
JESSICA YELLIN, WHO'S JOINING ME
HERE RIGHT NOW.
THE PRESIDENT, WE BELIEVE, IS
ALREADY INSIDE THE HIGH SCHOOL,
YES?
>> YES, HE'S GRIEVING AND
COMFORTING FAMILIES WHO HAVE
LOST LOVED ONES.
>> AND THE SERVICE IS TO START
AT 7:00.
HE'LL ALSO BE SPEAKING THERE.
>> HE'LL BE SPEAKING, AND I'M
TOLD THAT THE PRESIDENT HAS
HIMSELF BEEN WORKING ON THESE
REMARKS.
HE'S TAKEN IT PERSONALLY AND
BEEN PREPARING THEM, EVEN ON HIS
WAY UP HERE, ANDERSON.
TOLD THAT THE REMARKS WILL SPEAK
TO THE NATION'S OBLIGATIONS TO
OUR CHILDREN.
THIS IS A PRESIDENT WHO OFTEN
STRUGGLES TO SHOW EMOTION, AND
WE SAW HIM SO UNUSUALLY
EMOTIONAL ON FRIDAY.
SOME OF THE PEOPLE CLOSEST TO
HIM TELL ME IT'S BECAUSE THIS
TRAGEDY HAS TOUCHED HIM AS MUCH
AS ANY EVENT IN HIS POLITICAL
LIFE, AND WE SAW THAT WHEN HE
CAME OUT TO THE BRIEFING ROOM
AND ADDRESSED IT.
HERE'S A LITTLE BIT OF WHAT HE
SAID.
>> SO OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN
TODAY FOR THE PARENTS AND
GRANDPARENTS, SISTERS AND
BROTHERS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN AND FOR THE FAMILIES OF
THE ADULTS WHO WERE LOST.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN FOR THE
PARENTS OF THE SURVIVORS AS
WELL, FOR AS BLESSED AS THEY ARE
TO HAVE THEIR CHILDREN HOME
TONIGHT, THEY KNOW THAT THEIR
CHILDREN'S INNOCENCE HAS BEEN
TORN AWAY FROM THEM TOO EARLY,
AND THERE ARE NO WORDS THAT WILL
EASE THEIR PAIN.
>> IT REALLY WAS REMARKABLE TO
SEE THE PRESIDENT LIKE THAT.
HE DID INTIMATE THE POSSIBILITY
OF SOMETHING REALLY INTO GUN
CONTROL.
HE DIDN'T USE THE WORDS GUN
CONTROL, BUT HE TALKED ABOUT
SOME SORT OF CHANGE.
>> HE SAID IT'S TIME TO TAKE
MEANINGFUL ACTION, AND HE DIDN'T
SPECIFY WHAT THAT IS TO HIM.
HE DID VOW TO STAND FOR THE
REPEAL OF THE ASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN IN HIS FIRST TERM.
HE DID NOT PRESS FOR THAT, TO
CLOSE THE GUN SHOW LOOPHOLE.
HE NEVER PRESSED FOR THAT.
THOSE ARE TWO ACTIONS HE COULD
TAKE.
THERE'S ALSO THE QUESTION, WILL
HE PURSUE SOME SORT OF MENTAL
HEALTH REFORMS?
IT'S INTERESTING HE WILL NEVER
HAVE TO STAND FOR RE-ELECTION.
HE DOESN'T HAVE TO FIGHT THE GUN
LOBBY.
THAT'S SOMETHING DEMOCRATS OFTEN
CONTEND WITH.
SO WE'LL SEE WHAT HE PRESSES
FOR, AND THAT'S ONE OF THE BIG
CHALLENGES TONIGHT.
YOU KNOW, ANDERSON, FOR HIM HE
HAS TO EXPRESS THE NATION'S
GRIEF, BUT THE MORE EFFECTIVE HE
IS AT CAPTURING THE NATION'S
EMOTIONS TONIGHT, THE MORE
PEOPLE WILL TURN TO HIM AS THE
PERSON WHO IS THE SYMBOL OF
SOLVING THIS PROBLEM, THE MORE
EFFECTIVE HE CAN BE AT
ADVOCATING WHATEVER POLICY HE
CHOOSES TO PURSUE IN THE WAKE OF
THIS TRAGEDY.
>> AND THE WHOLE MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUE IS SOMETHING THAT IS SO
RARELY ADDRESSED.
IT'S TREATED SO DIFFERENTLY THAN
OTHER FORMS OF ILLNESS.
WE'LL SEE IF THIS EVENT DOES
CHANGE THAT IN SOME WAY.
>> AND IT WAS A NATURAL ONE FOR
HIS GOOD FRIEND TED KENNEDY.
WE'LL SEE IF THAT HELPS HIM.
>> ALL OF THAT WILL TAKE PLACE
AT 7:00.
LET'S GO BACK TO WOLF.
>> ANDERSON, LET'S GET MORE NOW
ON THE FIRST VICTIM OF THIS
RAMPAGE, THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER
NANCY LANZA.
CNN'S ERIN BURNETT SAT DOWN WITH
FRIENDS OF NANCY LANZA AT A
RESTAURANT SHE PATRONIZED
SEVERAL TIMES A WEEK.
THEY SAID THAT NANCY DIDN'T HAVE
A REGULAR DAY JOB BUT DEDICATED
HER TIME TO CHARITY WORK.
>> WHEN DID YOU FIRST MEET
NANCY?
>> 12, 13 YEARS AGO.
MET HER RIGHT HERE IN THE BAR.
SHE'D COME IN HERE AND HAVE
TAKEOUT FOOD, AND WE GOT TO KNOW
EACH OTHER.
WE USED TO TALK IN THE BAR.
JUST LIKE CLICKED, AND THAT WAS
IT.
YOU KNOW, JUST STARTED TALKING
AND WE BECAME GOOD FRIENDS.
>> SHE WAS VERY FRIENDLY,
OUTGOING.
SHE WAS FUNNY.
WE TOOK TO HER.
SO, YEAH, SHE JUST BECAME FAST
FRIENDS WITH US.
SHE DID A LOT IN TOWN, WAS
ALWAYS ON THE GO.
>> GIVEN THAT YOU KNEW HER AS A
PERSON AND SOME OF THE THINGS
YOU'VE BEEN HEARING AS THE
COUNTRY STARTED TO LEARN A
LITTLE BIT ABOUT HER, WHAT DO
YOU THINK SOME OF THE BIGGEST
MISCONCEPTIONS ARE THAT YOU'VE
HEARD ON THE NEWS?
>> I THINK MOSTLY THE -- BETWEEN
THE CONDITION THAT HE HAD, WHICH
PEOPLE COULD CONFUSE FOR BEING
THE REASON, AND THE GUNS.
YOU KNOW, WE -- WE DON'T THINK
THAT HAS ANYTHING TO DO WITH HER
CHARACTER.
>> SHE DONATED HER TIME FOR ALL
CHARITABLE WORK, HELPING PEOPLE
THAT NEEDED HELP.
HELPING AIDS PEOPLE, DONATE
MONEY FOR AIDS AND CHARITIES.
THAT'S WHAT SHE DID.
SHE DIDN'T GET PAID FOR DOING
WHAT SHE DID.
ALL CHARITABLE WORK.
SHE DID IT ALL ON HER OWN.
>> VERY GENEROUS.
>> VERY GENEROUS PERSON.
A PERSON COULD BE SITTING HERE
AND JUST SAY YOU'RE TALKING TO
HER, AND THEY JUST HAPPEN TO BE
SAYING, I DON'T HAVE ANY MONEY
FOR THIS OR ANY MONEY FOR THAT,
SHE'D TAKE OUT HER CHECKBOOK AND
WRITE A CHECK OUT AND GIVE IT TO
THE PERSON WITHOUT EVEN KNOWING
THEM.
THAT'S THE KIND OF PERSON SHE
WAS.
>> JUST KIND.
>> SHE WAS A GENEROUS, KIND
PERSON.
>> SHOOTER KILLED HIS MOTHER.
SHE WAS THE FIRST VICTIM OF THIS
BRUTAL, BRUTAL MASSACRE.
WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT SOME
OF THE OTHER VICTIMS AS WELL.
BROOK BALDWIN IS JOINING US ONCE
AGAIN.
THESE STORIES ARE SO, SO HEART
WRENCHING, EACH AND EVERY ONE.
26 PEOPLE, 6 ADULTS, ALL WOMEN,
20 KIDS, ALL FIRST GRADERS.
>> Reporter: IT IS ABSOLUTELY
GUT WRENCHING WHEN YOU START
HEARING ABOUT THE STORIES OF
THESE YOUNGSTERS.
I JUST WANT TO LET YOU KNOW, ONE
OF THE GRANDPARENTS, A
GRANDFATHER OF TWO YOUNG KIDS
WHO WERE ACTUALLY IN VICKI
DESO
DESOTO'S FIRST GRADE CLASS JUST
CAME UP TO ME.
HE DIDN'T WANT TO GO ON CAMERA,
BUT HE SAID THE FIRST THING HIS
GRANDDAUGHTER SAID AFTER RUNNING
PAST THE GUNMAN AND SURVIVING
WAS SHE WANTED TO SEE THE
PRESIDENT TONIGHT.
UNFORTUNATELY, IT'S A CAPACITY
CROWD, AND SHE COULDN'T GET IN.
SHE ABSOLUTELY REFUSES TO GO
BACK TO SCHOOL ON WEDNESDAY,
ACCORDING TO THIS GRANDPARENT.
WE ARE LEARNING MORE AND MORE
ABOUT THESE LITTLE LIVES LOST.
I JUST WANT TO BEGIN WITH
SOMEONE THAT A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE
TALKING ABOUT BECAUSE WE HEARD
FROM HER FATHER.
SHE WAS EMILIE PARKER, 6 YEARS
OLD.
NOT A DRY EYE WHEN EVERYONE WAS
HEARING THE DETAILS OF HER LIFE
FROM HER YOUNG FATHER.
ACCORDING TO HER FATHER, HE SAID
EMILIE WAS THE TYPE OF PERSON
WHO COULD LIGHT UP A ROOM.
SHE WAS BRIGHT.
SHE WAS CREATIVE.
SHE WAS LOVING.
HER LAUGHTER WAS INFECTIOUS.
SHE WAS THE OLDEST OF THREE
LITTLE GIRLS, AND HER FATHER
SAID THAT EMILIE WAS A MENTOR
THIS THEM.
THEY LOOKED UP TO HER.
THEY'RE WONDERING WHERE THEIR
SISTER IS.
JESSICA RICO, 6 YEARS OLD.
SHE WAS THE FIRST BORN.
SHE WAS THEIR ROCK.
SHE WAS REFERRED TO AS THE CEO.
SHE DID ALL THE DETAILING.
SHE LOVED THE FAMILY OUTINGS AND
GOT TO PLAN THEM.
SHE LOVED HORSES, LIKE EVERY
6-YEAR-OLD GIRL.
SHE WAS DRAWING HORSES AND LOVED
TO WATCH HORSE MOVIES.
SHE ASKED SANTA CLAUS, NOT TOO
LONG AGO, FOR THIS CHRISTMAS,
SHE WANTED COWGIRL BOOTS AND A
COWGIRL HAT.
SADLY, THOSE GIFTS WILL NOT BE
OPENED.
SHE HAS TWO LITTLE BROTHERS, AND
HER BABY BROTHER TRAVIS DOESN'T
UNDERSTAND WHY HE CAN'T PLAY
WITH HIS BEST FRIEND.
ONE MORE, OLIVIA ENGEL, 6.
FAMILY SAYS SHE WAS PRECOCIOUS
AND COMPLETELY ENDEARING.
NOTHING WAS OFF LIMITS FOR HER.
SHE LOVED BALLET.
SHE LOVED TO SWIM.
SHE LOVED SOCCER.
SHE LOVED GIRL SCOUTS.
AND HER FAVORITE COLORS WERE
PINK AND PURPLE.
AND EVERY NIGHT, WOLF AND
ANDERSON, SHE LED THE TABLE AT
DINNER WITH GRACE.
THESE ARE JUST 3 OF THE 20
YOUNGSTERS WHO ARE NO LONGER
WITH US HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> EVERY ONE OF THESE KIDS SO,
SO BEAUTIFUL, SO ADORABLE, AND
UNFORTUNATELY, SO TRAGIC.
WHAT A WAY TO BE FOR THEIR LIVES
TO END SO PREMATURELY.
FOR OUR VIEWERS WHO WOULD LIKE
TO HELP, THEY CAN DO SO, THEY
CAN ONCE AGAIN GO TO
CNN.COM/IMPACT, AND THEY'LL HAVE
A CHANCE TO IMPACT OUR WORLD.
SANJAY IS HERE WITH US AS WELL.
SANJAY, MENTAL HEALTH, IT'S A
HUGE PROBLEM IN THIS COUNTRY.
THIS SHOOTER OBVIOUSLY HAD
MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES.
I DON'T KNOW IF HE WAS TREATED
FOR THIS.
I DON'T KNOW IF HE WAS ON
MEDICATION.
THEY DID RELEASE THE AUTOPSY
RESULTS TODAY.
>> AS EXPECTED, IT WASN'T GOING
TO PROVIDE ANSWERS AS FAR AS IF
THERE'S ANYTHING SPECIFICALLY
THAT COULD EXPLAIN THIS.
I THINK WE KNOW THAT HE
COMMITTED SUICIDE.
THEY WANTED TO CONFIRM THAT AS
PART OF THE AUTOPSY, BUT THAT
WAS REALLY ABOUT IT.
BUT YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
THIS WHOLE NOTION OF MENTAL
HEALTH, BEING ON PAR OR HAVING
PARITY, AS WE CALL IT, WITH
PHYSICAL DISEASES, WITH HEART
DISEASE, WITH DIABETES, CANCER,
WHATEVER IT IS.
IN THOSE SITUATIONS, WOLF, WE
KNOW WE CAN SEND SOMEONE TO A
DOCTOR OR THEY CAN GET CARE.
>> IF YOU HAVE A TEMPERATURE, IF
YOU HAVE THE FLU, YOU'RE
COUGHING, YOU TREAT IT.
BUT SOMETIMES PARENTS SEE MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES, AND THEY DON'T DO
WHAT THEY NEED TO DO.
>> I THINK IT'S A VERY IMPORTANT
POINT BECAUSE PEOPLE SAY, LOOK,
THEY MISSED THE SIGNS, OR THEY
WERE IN DENIAL.
SOMETIMES IT MAY BE TRUE, BUT
OFTENTIMES, AS YOU'VE HEARD THE
STORIES OVER THE YEARS, PARENTS
HAVE A GREAT DEAL OF ANGUISH
OVER MAYBE IN THIS CASE THEIR
CHILD'S MENTAL HEALTH, BUT THERE
ISN'T MUCH THAT THEY CAN DO.
I MEAN, THE RESOURCES AREN'T
THERE NECESSARILY, EITHER IN THE
MEDICAL SENSE OR JUST HAVING
ENOUGH PHYSICIANS OR HAVING THE
OVERALL INFRASTRUCTURE TO
SUPPORT THIS.
PART OF IT IS ALSO STIGMA.
IT STILL VERY MUCH EXISTS.
IT'S EXISTED FOR A LONG TIME.
WE'D LIKE TO THINK IT'S GETTING
BETTER, BUT THIS IDEA OF, IF YOU
GET TREATED FOR A MENTAL
ILLNESS, YOU'LL BE STAG MA
TIESED, AND IT WILL AFFECT YOU
FOR THE REST OF YOUR LIFE, NEEDS
TO BE DISPELLED.
YOU CAN GET TREATMENT.
>> THERE IS MEDICATION THAT
PEOPLE, YOUNG PEOPLE, TEENAGERS
AND ADULTS CAN TAKE, BUT A LOT
OF TIMES THEY JUST REFUSE TO
TAKE THE MEDICATION.
SOMETIMES THE RESULTS CAN BE
TRAGIC.
>> MEDICATIONS.
COGNITIVE THERAPY HAS BEEN SHOWN
TO BE EFFECTIVE IN THESE SORTS
OF THINGS.
GROUP THERAPY.
SOME OF IT WE'RE SEEING NOW,
THIS IS A VERY DIFFERENT
SITUATION, BUT THIS IDEA AGAIN
THAT MANY OF THESE PEOPLE WHO
ARE MENTAL ILLNESS, THEY'RE NOT
ALONE.
THEY CAN BENEFIT FROM BEING IN
SESSIONS WHERE IT'S SHOWN TO
THEM, THAT THEY HAVE GROUPS TO
SUPPORT.
BUT YOU'RE RIGHT.
THEY HAVE THINGS THAT CAN BE
DONE.
IT'S JUST A QUESTION OF MAKING A
SYSTEM POSSIBLE FOR THOSE
PEOPLE.
WE'RE NOT THERE.
I CAN TELL YOU THAT AS A
PHYSICIAN.
AND THE HOSPITALS ARE RIGHT,
WE'RE NOT THERE.
THAT PARITY IS SOMETHING THAT
NEEDS TO HAPPEN.
>> UNFORTUNATELY, A LOT OF THE
CHILDREN WHO WERE AT THIS
SCHOOL, CHILDREN ALL OVER THE
COUNTRY, THEY'RE GOING TO HAVE
SERIOUS ISSUES NOW DEALING WITH
THE FALLOUT FROM THIS.
>> POST-TRAUMATIC STRESS IS
SOMETHING THAT EXISTS IN
CHILDREN AS WELL.
AGAIN, WE THINK ABOUT IT
PRIMARILY IN ADULTS, BUT IT
MANIFESTS.
IT DISPLAYS IN DIFFERENT WAYS.
CHILDREN MAY REGRESS A BIT, THEY
MAY NOT TALK ABOUT IT.
SLEEP IS SO IMPORTANT.
YOU CAN PREDIBLLINGT -- IT'S A
VERY POWERFUL PREDICTOR OF HOW
CHILDREN AND ADULTS ALIKE ARE
GOING TO DO BY HOW WELL THEY'RE
SLEEPING.
IF THERE'S SOMETHING THAT
PARENTS CAN DO TONIGHT AND THE
NEXT FEW NIGHTS AS THEY'RE
TALKING TO THEIR CHILDREN ABOUT
IT, MAKE SURE THEY'RE GETTING
SLEEP BECAUSE THAT'S GOING TO BE
A BIG POWERFUL PREDICTOR FOR
THEIR FUTURE.
>> WE'RE ONLY MOMENTS AWAY FROM
THIS PRAYER VIGIL.
THE FOLKS ARE THERE.
THE PRESIDENT IS MEETING WITH
SOME OF THE FAMILIES NOW, THE
PARENTS OF THE VICTIMS, SOME OF
THE OTHERS, FIRST RESPONDERS.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE EXTENSIVE
LIVE COVERAGE.
YOU CAN SEE WHAT'S GOING ON
RIGHT NOW OVER AT THE HIGH
SCHOOL HERE IN NEWTOWN.
WE'LL TAKE A QUICK BREAK, RESUME
OUR COVERAGE RIGHT AFTER THIS.
♪ OOH BABY, LOOKS LIKE
YOU NEED A LITTLE HELP THERE ♪
♪ OOH BABY,
CAN I DO FOR YOU TODAY? ♪
[ Female Announcer ] NEED HELP
KEEPING YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE?
ALIGN CAN HELP.
ONLY ALIGN HAS BIFANTIS,
A PATENTED PROBIOTIC
THAT NATURALLY HELPS MAINTAIN
YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE.
TRY ALIGN TO HELP RETAIN
A BALANCED DIGESTIVE SYSTEM.
TRY THE #1 GASTROENTEROLOGIST
RECOMMENDED PROBIOTIC.
ALIGN.
We are gathered here today to
celebrate the union of
Tim and Laura.
It's amazing how appreciative
ople are when you tell them
they could save a lot of money
on their car insurance
by switching to GEICO...they may
even make you their best man.
May I have the rings please?
Ah, Helzberg Diamonds.
Nice choice, Mate.
...and now in the presence
of these guests
we join this loving couple.
Oh dear...
GEICO. 15 minutes could save you
15% or more on car insurance.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO OUR
CONTINUING COVERAGE.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT A TOWN, NATION
IN MOURNING.
THE PRESIDENT IS LIVE AT NEWTOWN
HIGH SCHOOL.
YOU'RE LOOKING INSIDE WHERE
HUNDREDS HAVE GATHERED.
MANY HUNDREDS MORE STILL OUTSIDE
WAITING FOR THE BEGINNING OF
THIS INTERFAITH PRAYER SERVICE.
THAT'S TO START AT 7:00 EASTERN
TIME.
WE'RE GOING TO BE BRINGING THAT
TO YOU LIVE WITHOUT
INTERRUPTION.
WE'LL NOT BE TALKING OVER IT.
IT WILL ALL JUST PLAYING OUT AS
THE PEOPLE INSIDE ARE HEARING
IT, YOU AT HOME IT CAN HEAR IT
AND TAKE PART IN IT AS WELL.
THE PRESIDENT IS AT THE SCHOOL
IN CLASSROOMS, MEETING WITH
VARIOUS FAMILY MEMBERS WHO HAVE
LOST FAMILY MEMBERS ATS THE
SCHOOL.
TEACHERS AND ADMINISTRATORS AS
WELL WHO HAVE LOST THEIR LIVES,
THEIR FAMILIES HERE IN NEWTOWN
SIMPLY OVERWHELMED WITH RELIEF
AND GRATITUDE.
THEIR CHILDREN WERE INSIDE THE
SCHOOL.
THEY MADE IT OUT ALIVE.
AMONG THEM, THE LIKATAS WHOSE
SON AIDAN RAN PAST THE SHOOTER
AND ESCAPED.
NOW THEY'RE GRAPPLING WITH THE
IDEA OF TELLING THEIR YOUNG SON
HIS TEACHER IS GONE.
LISTEN TO WHAT THEY HAD TO SAY.
WE'LL GET YOU THAT SOUND A
LITTLE BIT.
AIDAN'S TEACHER WAS VICTORIA
SOTO, WHO PLACED HERSELF IN
FRONT OF HER STUDENTS BEFORE THE
GUNMAN SHOT HER.
SHE TOLD THE GUNMAN HER STUDENTS
WEREN'T IN THE CLASSROOM.
DON LEMON IS IN NEWTOWN BY ONE
OF THE MANY MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS
WE SAW SPRING UP.
HE'S BEEN TALKING TO PEOPLE ALL
EVENING LONG.
IT REALLY STRIKES ME, DON, A LOT
OF PEOPLE AREN'T JUST FROM
NEWTOWN.
THEY'RE FROM OTHER PARTS OF
CONNECTICUT WHO HAVE COME HERE
TO BEAR WITNESS, TO BE PART OF
THIS AND TO PAY THEIR RESPECTS
TO THOSE WHO LOST THEIR LIVES.
>> YEAH, A COLLECTIVE HUG IS
WHAT YOU COULD CALL IT.
AND WE'RE HERE IN THE TOWN
SQUARE, NEWTOWN TOWN SQUARE, AND
IT'S REALLY LIT UP LIKE A
CHRISTMAS VILLAGE HERE.
THAT'S A TAVERN BACK THERE.
AND THEN YOU SEE THE TOWN CENTER
THERE, AND JUST BEYOND THAT,
POLICE ACTIVITY THAT SORT OF
RUINS THE WHOLE CHRISTMAS SPIRIT
AND THE IDYLLIC LOOK IN THIS
WHOLE TOWN.
EVERYONE IS GATHERED AROUND THE
CHRISTMAS TREE AND HANGING OUT
WITH THEIR FRIENDS, BUT THEY'RE
ALL GATHERED AROUND THE
TELEVISION SETS AWAITING WORD
FROM THE PRESIDENT.
THEY'RE ACTUALLY DOWN HERE
TONIGHT BECAUSE THEY WANT TO BE
PART OF THIS.
THIS IS WHERE THE MEDIA IS
CAMPED OUT.
THAT'S WHERE THE METHODIST
CHURCH IS WHERE YOU AND I WERE
LAST NIGHT, ANDERSON.
AND THIS CHRISTMAS TREE HERE
EVERY YEAR, IT'S A BIG CHRISTMAS
TREE, AND THERE IS MAKESHIFT
MEMORIAL THAT WE HAVE BEEN
TALKING ABOUT.
IT'S GROWING BY THE MINUTE HERE.
THERE'S SO MANY STUFFED ANIMALS
AND THINGS THEY PILED ON TOP OF
EACH OTHER.
THEY'RE MAKING SURE ALL THE
CANDLES ARE LIT.
SOMEONE COMES BY WITH A LIGHTER
JUST TO MAKE SURE.
THIS GENTLEMAN IS STANDING BY
HERE.
YOU'VE LIVED IN THIS COMMUNITY
YOUR WHOLE LIFE?
>> YES.
>> Reporter: WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
>> CHRIS SIEMEN.
MY FAMILY'S BEEN HERE SINCE THE
1930s, AND I'VE LIVED HERE MY
WHOLE LIFE.
IT'S DEVASTATING.
THERE'S NO WORDS.
IT'S A NIGHTMARE, A COMPLETE
NIGHTMARE.
OUR TOWN WILL REBUILD.
>> Reporter: THIS IS NOT WHAT
YOU WANT THIS TOWN TO BE
REMEMBERED FOR?
>> NO, NOT AT ALL.
WE'RE ON THE MAP FOR THE WRONG
REASONS.
IT'S JUST HORRIBLE.
>> Reporter: HOW ARE YOU AND CAN
YOU -- I IMAGINE THAT YOU WILL
RECOVER, BUT IT WILL NEVER BE
THE SAME HERE.
>> IT WILL NEVER BE THE SAME,
BUT DAY BY DAY, SAY OUR PRAYERS,
AND THINGS WILL GET BACK
TOGETHER EVENTUALLY.
>> Reporter: THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Reporter: WISH THE VERY BESTE
THESE STAY LIGHTED.
>> WE HAVE ALL GROWN UP HERE AND
WE FEEL THESE CANDLES NEED TO
STAY LIT.
THESE ARE FOR THE 26 GORGEOUS
ANGELS NOW IN HEAVEN, AND IT'S
OUR JOB TO TAKE CARE OF EVERYONE
IN IN TOWN, INCLUDING THIS
MEMORIAL.
>> Reporter: DID YOU GO TO
SCHOOL HERE?
>> YEAH, WE ALL DID.
>> Reporter: WHY DID YOU GO TO
SCHOOL?
>> WE WENT TO A COUPLE DIFFERENT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS, BUT WE ALL
WENT THROUGH THE NEWTOWN SCHOOL
SYSTEM ALL THE WAY THROUGH HIGH
SCHOOL.
>> Reporter: YOU FELT SAFE THEN,
BUT THINGS ARE DIFFERENT NOW.
>> THINGS ARE DIFFERENT, BUT
NOTHING CHANGES ABOUT THIS TOWN.
THIS TOWN IS A WONDERFUL,
BEAUTIFUL PLACE TO GROW UP IN,
AND, UNFORTUNATELY, THESE
BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN WILL NOT
EXPERIENCE WHAT WE'VE
EXPERIENCED, BUT OUR THOUGHTS
AND FEELINGS ABOUT THIS TOWN
HAVE NOT CHANGED.
WE WILL GET THROUGH THIS
TOGETHER.
>> Reporter: WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
>> SAMANTHA.
>> TAYLOR.
>> Reporter: THANK YOU, GUYS.
GOD BLESS YOU.
I WANT TO MOVE DOWN HERE AND
TALK TO SOME OF THESE FOLKS.
THESE GUYS, YOU'RE FROM A
NEIGHBORING TOWN?
>> YEAH.
>> Reporter: AND THEY'RE RIVALS,
MAYBE SPORTS RIVALS, BUT TONIGHT
YEAR ALL TOGETHER?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
WE'RE ALL IN THIS TOGETHER.
WHEN SOMETHING LIKE THIS
HAPPENS, I MEAN, TOWNS AROUND
HERE ARE REALLY CLOSE.
WE JUST PULL TOGETHER FOR EACH
OTHER.
YOU KNOW, THAT'S REALLY WHAT'S
IMPORTANT, AND AROUND, YOU KNOW,
THE HOLIDAY SEASON, I THINK IT'S
GREAT TO SEE SO MANY PEOPLE OUT
HERE FROM ALL OVER THE PLACE
SUPPORTING EACH OTHER.
YOU KNOW, IT HELPS A LITTLE BIT,
BUT CIRCUMSTANCES STILL TOUGH.
>> Reporter: WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
>> I'M ARDIAN.
>> Reporter: WHAT YOU DO YOU
PLAY?
>> FOOTBALL, SIR.
>> FOR WHICH TOWN?
>> NEW FAIRFIELD HIGH SCHOOL.
>> I PLAYED BASEBALL FOR NEW
FAIRFIELD AS WELL.
>> Reporter: WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
>> I'M TREVOR.
I PLAYED FOOTBALL AND TRACK.
I HAVE A LITTLE BROTHER WHO IS 8
YEARS OLD.
I CAN ONLY IMAGINE WHAT THE
FAMILIES ARE DEALING WITH NOW.
>> Reporter: WHERE WERE YOU WHEN
YOU FOUND OUT ABOUT THIS?
>> I WAS ACTUALLY AT MY HOUSE,
JUST GOT BACK FROM COLLEGE, AND
I THINK IT WAS ALL THE SAME
CIRCUMSTANCE FOR EVERYBODY ELSE,
TOO.
WE LOOKED AT OUR PHONES AND
REALIZED IT WAS HAPPENING.
WE REALIZED IT WAS A TOWN OVER
AND IT REALLY HIT HARD WHEN WE
KNEW LIKE SOME PEOPLE THAT ARE
INVOLVED AND EVERYTHING LIKE
THAT.
>> Reporter: I ASKED THE OTHER
GENTLEMAN, THIS IS NOT
SOMETHING -- OR SAID TO HIM THIS
IS NOT SOMETHING YOU WANT YOUR
TOWN OR THE TOWNS IN THIS AREA
OF CONNECTICUT TO BE KNOWN FOR.
>> NOT AT ALL.
IT'S JUST A TRAGEDY AND WE'RE
TRYING TO GO THROUGH IT
TOGETHER.
>> Reporter: THE ENTIRE WORLD IS
WATCHING TONIGHT, NOT JUST IN
THE UNITED STATES BUT OUR
VIEWERS FROM AROUND THE WORLD.
WHAT DO YOU WANT THEM TO KNOW
ABOUT THE PEOPLE HERE?
>> PEOPLE HERE ARE GREAT.
JUST AN AREA FILLED WITH
WONDERFUL PEOPLE.
I COULDN'T BE BLESSED WITH
BETTER NEIGHBORS THAN I HAVE.
I HAVE TONS OF ROLE MODELS
STARTING WITH MY FRIENDS, MY
TEACHERS, MY FAMILY.
I THINK EVERYONE AROUND HERE IS
FAMILY.
YOU KNOW, YOU CAN'T BASE -- YOU
CAN'T JUDGE A TOWN OR PEOPLE
BASED ON AN OCCURRENCE LIKE
THIS.
YOU KNOW, YOU KIND OF GOT TO
JUDGE THEM BASED ON HOW THEY
HANDLE IT AND MOVE FORWARD.
I THINK WE'RE DEFINITELY DOING
THAT AND IT'S WONDERFUL TO SEE.
>> Reporter: THANK YOU, GUYS.
WE'RE GOING TO MOVE THIS WAY, IF
YOU CAN WALK AROUND HERE.
THIS IS ONE OF THE MANY
CHRISTMAS TREES THAT PEOPLE HAVE
JUST BEEN DROPPING OFF,
CHRISTMAS TREES, AND WE SPOKE
EARLIER TO THE FAMILY THAT
DROPPED THIS OFF AND THE
GENTLEMAN, THE HUSBAND IS AN
ELECTRICIAN BY TRADE AND HE PUT
THIS TREE TOGETHER AND THIS IS
THE NAMES OF ALL OF THE CHILDREN
WHO DIED IN THE SCHOOL, AND
THERE ARE OTHER CHRISTMAS TREES
THAT HAVE BEEN PUT UP HERE.
THE BIG ONE OFF TO MY LEFT HERE,
THAT'S HERE EVERY YEAR, BUT THE
SMALLER ONES ARE TO HONOR THE
VICTIMS.
WHERE ARE YOU FROM?
>> TRUMBULL, CONNECTICUT.
>> WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
>> NINA.
>> Reporter: YOU'RE HERE
BECAUSE?
>> I JUST WANTED COME OUT AND
SUPPORT THE FAMILIES.
>> Reporter: YOU COULDN'T SIT AT
HOME?
>> NO, I COULDN'T SIT AT HOME.
I WENT TO SEE THE PRESIDENT BUT
THE TRAFFIC IS JUST TOO MUCH
TRAFFIC DOWN THERE.
>> Reporter: WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
>> I'M MARY JONES FROM
BRIDGEPORT, CONNECTICUT.
>> Reporter: I SAID EARLIER THAT
PEOPLE HERE WANT TO COME OUT
BECAUSE THEY DON'T WANT TO FEEL
HELPLESS.
DOES THIS HELP?
>> YES, IT DOES.
IT DOES.
INSTEAD OF JUST SITTING THERE
AND WATCHING IT ON THE TV.
IT'S MUCH BETTER TO JUST BE
AMONG AND TO SHOW THE SUPPORT
AND THE LOVE THAT WE HAVE FOR
THEM.
>> Reporter: I DON'T KNOW IF
THERE'S ANYTHING GOOD THAT CAN
COME OUT OF THIS, BUT IF THERE
IS, WHAT IS IT?
>> LIKE YOU SAID, WE DON'T KNOW
IF THERE'S ANYTHING GOOD THAT
CAN COME OUT OF IT.
JUST HAVE TO PRAY, PRAY FOR THE
FAMILIES, PRAY FOR EVERYONE.
THERE'S NOTHING THAT WE CAN
REALLY DO BUT PRAY.
YOU KNOW.
>> Reporter: THANK YOU, LADIES.
WE'RE GOING TO MOVE BACK HERE.
THANK YOU.
WE'RE GOING TO MOVE BACK HERE
AND YOU SEE THESE GUYS OVER
HERE?
THEY'RE BRINGING THEIR CANDLES
AND THEY'RE LIGHTING THEM.
DO YOU MIND IF WE TALK TO YOU?
>> NO, ACTUALLY.
I PROSECUTEFER NOT TO.
>> THE SAME OVER HERE.
SORRY ABOUT THAT.
>> Reporter: IT'S OKAY.
IF PEOPLE DON'T WANT TO TALK TO
US, WE DON'T DO IT.
WE WANT TO BE RESPECTFUL.
YOU SEE THEM HUGGING EACH OTHER.
THAT'S THE SENTIMENT, PEOPLE
HUGGING AND CRYING AND PRAYING
AND JUST SENDING WELL WISHES,
ANDERSON, AND THAT'S THE SPIRIT
OF THIS PARTICULAR COMMUNITY
HERE.
THEY WANT TO SHOW THEIR SUPPORT,
AND, AGAIN, THEY DON'T WANT TO
FEEL HELPLESS, THEY WANT TO FEEL
USEFUL AND COME OUT AND SHOW HOW
MUCH THEY LOVE THIS TOWN AND
THAT THEY DON'T WANT THIS TOWN
TO BE REMEMBERED FOR THIS
PARTICULAR TRAGEDY.
INSTEAD, A TOWN THAT PULLED
TOGETHER WHEN A TRAGEDY
HAPPENED.
>> YEAH.
AND WE ARE -- WE'RE REALLY JUST
MOMENTS AWAY FROM THE START OF
THIS SERVICE.
THE HIGH SCHOOL WHERE THE
SERVICE IS SET TO BEGIN, I CAN
TELL YOU STILL WHOLE FAMILIES
ARE STILL ARRIVING HERE HOPING
TO GET INSIDE.
PEOPLE ARE BRINGING THEIR LITTLE
CHILDREN, JUST WALKING BY.
THEY PASS BY A SMALLER MAKESHIFT
MEMORIAL THAT'S BEEN SET UP
OUTSIDE THE SCHOOL AND WALK
TOWARDS THE SCHOOL.
THERE'S A LONG LINE THAT'S
SLOWLY MOVING INTO THE
AUDITORIUM THERE, BUT AS YOU CAN
SEE, IT IS ALREADY FULL UP.
THE PRESIDENT IS INSIDE THE
SCHOOL AS WELL ALREADY MEETING
WITH FAMILY MEMBERS.
THE SERVICE IS SET TO BEGIN AT
7:00 EASTERN TIME, AND WE, OF
COURSE, WILL BRING THAT TO YOU
LIVE, AND THERE HE SUE SENATOR
LIEBERMAN TALKING TO A NUMBER OF
PEOPLE INSIDE, WOLF.
>> YOU SEE, ANDERSON, YOU SAW
THE OUTGOING SENATOR LIEBERMAN
OF CONNECTICUT SPEAKING WITH
REPRESENTATIVES FROM THE CLERGY.
THIS SERVICE, WE NOW HAVE SOME
DETAILS OF WHAT IS ABOUT TO
BEGIN ONCE THE PRESIDENT GETS
THERE.
REPRESENTATIVES OF I THINK MOST
OF THE MAJOR FAITHS HERE IN THE
UNITED STATES WILL BE
PARTICIPATING, PATRIOT
PROTESTANTS, CATHOLICS, FROM THE
JEWISH RELIGION.
THERE WILL BE A REPRESENTATIVE
FROM THE ISLAMIC CENTER HERE.
ALSO SOMEONE FROM THE BAHA'I
TRADITION WILL BE HERE AS WELL.
WE WILL BE HEARING BRIEF
PASSAGES FROM ALL OF THEM AND,
OF COURSE, THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES WILL BE SPEAKING
AS WELL.
HE'S NOW COMFORTING.
HE'S NOW MEETING WITH SOME OF
THE FAMILIES.
THE FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS, THE
YOUNG KIDS, THE ADULTS WHO WERE
TRAGICALLY GUNNED DOWN AT THAT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL FRIDAY
MORNING.
CNN ATTENDED EED THE FIRST MEET
OF THETOWN UNITED.
TELL US WHAT THAT'S FOLKS ARE
HOPING TO ACCOMPLISH IN THIS
SMALL COMMUNITY.
>> Reporter: REMEMBER, EVERYONE
HERE IS GRIEVING, AND EVEN THE
PEOPLE WHO NEW CHILDREN WHO
DIED, THESE ARE PEOPLE, PARENTS,
WHO ARE FRIENDS WITH THE
PATIENTS OF THE CHILDREN WHO
DIED IN THAT ROOM.
THEY SAY, YES, TONIGHT THEY ARE
THE BACKDROP OF A NATION THAT IS
MOURNING, THE BACKDROP OF A
PRESIDENT WHO WILL PLAY
COMFORTER IN CHIEF, BUT TOMORROW
WHAT THEY DON'T WANT LOST, WHAT
THEY DON'T WANT TO BECOME IS
JUST ANOTHER HEADLINE.
THEY WANT A TRUE NATIONAL
DISCUSSION TOMORROW ABOUT
DIFFICULT ISSUES, DIFFICULT
ISSUES LIKE THE PROLIFERATION OF
GUNS AND MENTAL ILLNESS.
HERE IS WHAT THIS GROUP TOLD US.
>> WE LIVE IN AN INCREASINGLY
VOUORISTIC SOCIETY THAT HAS
BECOME MORE DISTANT FROM EACH
OTHER ON PERSONAL AND
INTERPERSONAL LEVEL, AND THAT'S
HOW SOMEBODY CAN FEEL SO DISTANT
FROM OTHER PEOPLE THAT THEY
COULD ACTUALLY SHOOT CHILDREN.
>> COMMUNICATION IN THIS COUNTRY
IS BROKEN.
THE POLITICAL SYSTEM, WE CANNOT
FIND COMMON GROUND TO TALK ABOUT
ANYTHING IT SEEMS LIKE THESE
DAYS, AND IF THIS IS A TRIGGER
POINT OR A TIPPING POINT FOR US
AND OUR ELECTED OFFICIALS TO
ACTUALLY START TALKING TO EACH
OTHER IN A WAY THAT'S RESPECTFUL
AND RESULTS IN REAL CHANGE, THAT
WOULD BE HUGE.
>> Reporter: YOU CAN HEAR HOW
FRUSTRATED THEY ARE.
THEY ARE EXTREMELY FRUSTRATED.
THEY ARE STILL HEART BROKEN, BUT
THEY SAY THAT THEY WANT TO ENACT
SOME SORT OF CHANGE.
THEY FEEL THAT MANY PEOPLE IN
AMERICA FEEL THE SAME WAY THAT
THEY DO.
THEY SAY THE BEST WAY TO CHANNEL
THEIR GRIEF IS TO LEAD TO SOME
CHANGE.
THEY DON'T KNOW HOW TO DO THIS,
WOLF.
THEY ARE HOPING THOUGH TO LEARN
ALONG THE WAY AND THAT THE REST
OF THE COUNTRY WILL JOIN THEM.
WOLF?
>> THANKS VERY MUCH.
SANJAY GUPTA IS WATCHING WHAT'S
GOING ON.
HE'S HERE WITH ME AS WELL.
THE PEOPLE WHO ARE THERE AT THE
AUDITORIUM IN THIS HIGH SCHOOL
RIGHT DOWN THE STLEREET, THESE E
PEOPLE WHO HAVE JUST COME OUT,
THEY WANT TO PARTICIPATE IN
THIS, THEY WANT TO REMEMBER WHAT
HAPPENED AND THEN MOVE ON, BUT
IT'S NOT GOING TO BE EASY FOR
THIS COMMUNITY.
SCHOOL IS SUPPOSED TO RESUME
TOMORROW MORNING.
A LOT OF PARENTS, THEY'RE GOING
TO BE RELUCTANT PRESUMABLY TO
SEND THEIR KIDS TO SCHOOL.
>> YOU HAVE TO ASSUME IN THIS
DAY AND AGE THAT EVEN FOR THE
WEEKEND, IF YOU