>>> I'M ERIN BURNETTE REPORTING
LIVE IF NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
A COMMUNITY IN MOURNING AFTER A
DEADLY SCHOOL SHOOTING KILLED 20
CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS, OVER
THE NEXT TWO HOURS WE BRING YOU
THE LATEST DETAILS ON THE
INVESTIGATION AND THE VICTIMS.
AND THERE ARE ALSO SOME OTHER
MAJOR STORIES THAT WE'RE
FOLLOWING ON THIS SUNDAY
AFTERNOON.
DEB FERRICK IS LIVE IN ATLANTA
AND WILL BRING YOU THE
DEVELOPMENTS LATER IN THE
PROGRAM.
AS WE ARRIVED HERE WHERE OUR
CAMERAS ARE, IT'S HARD NOT TO BE
MOVED BY WHAT YOU SEE IN THIS
TOWN.
THERE'S ONE PLACE WHERE YOU
LITERALLY SEE 20 ANGELS IN WOOD.
EVERYWHERE, THERE ARE BALLOONS
AND FLOWERS AND TEDDY BEARS AND
THINGS IN HONOR OF VICTIMS THAT
IT IS IMPOSSIBLE TO IMAGINE.
THE AGE AND INNOCENCE OF THESE
VICTIMS.
TODAY WE'RE LEARNING SOME NEW
DETAILS ABOUT THE HORRENDOUS
CRIME AND ABOUT THESE INNOCENT
VICTIMS' DEATHS.
HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW.
POLICE SAY CRIME SCENE
INVESTIGATORS ARE WRAPPING UP
WORK IN THE PARKING LOT OF THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
WORK CONTINUES INSIDE THE
SCHOOL, THE CRIME SCENE.
HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW ABOUT THE
GUNS.
THREE OF THEM WERE FOUND NEXT TO
THE BODY OF THE SUSPECTED
GUNMAN.
HIS NAME OF COURSE IS ADAM
LANZA, 20 YEARS OLD.
OFFICIALS SAY ONE WAS THE
PRIMARY WEAPON USED AND IT WAS A
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE.
WE HAVE ALSO LEARNED THAT THE 20
CHILDREN WHO WERE KILLED INSIDE
THE SCHOOL WERE SHOT MULTIPLE
TIMES.
EVERY SINGLE ONE OF THEM WAS
EITHER SIX OR SEVEN YEARS OLD.
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS GOING TO
ARRIVE HERE IN NEWTOWN THIS
AFTERNOON TO TRY TO COMFORT THE
VICTIMS' FAMILIES.
HE'S SCHEDULED TO ARRIVE HERE IN
ABOUT AN HOUR AND A HALF.
HE IS GOING TO BE MEETING WITH
THE FAMILIES AND ALSO WITH THE
FIRST RESPONDERS.
AND AFTER THAT HE'S GOING TO BE
SPEAKING AT AN INTERFAITH VIGIL.
WE'RE GOING TO BE TAKING THAT
VIGIL HERE ON CNN LIVE IN ITS
ENTIRETY.
IT BEGINS AT 7:00 EASTERN TIME.
WE DO KNOW THE NAMES OF THE
VICTIMS TODAY.
BUT WE ARE STILL LEARNING ABOUT
WHO THEY WERE, WHAT THEIR LIVES
WERE LIKE.
SO SHORT, BUT NO DOUBT GIVEN
THEIR AGE, PROVIDING SO MUCH JOY
FOR THOSE AROUND THEM.
NICK VALENCIA IS IN THE CNN NEWS
ROOM IN ATLANTA.
I KNOW THE FAMILIES ARE STARTING
POST PICTURES OF THEIR FAMILICH
AND ISSUE STATEMENTS.
>> SOME OF THE FAMILIES HAVE
BEEN VERY PRIVATE ABOUT THEIR
LOSS.
BUT SOME REALLY WANT PEOPLE TO
KNOW ABOUT THEIR LOVED ONES.
THE FAMILY OF JESSE ARECOS --
JESSICA REKOS SAID THIS --
JESSICA LOVED HORSES, SHE SPENT
MOST OF HER TIME DEVOTED TO
THEM, WATCHING HORSE MOVIES,
DRAWING THEM, READING AND
WRITING ABOUT THEM.
THIS CHRISTMAS SHE ASKED SANTA
FOR NEW COW GIRL BOOTS AND A COW
GIRL HAT.
SHE LOVED PLAYING, AS MOST
LITTLE KIDS DO.
SHE LOVED PLAYING WITH HER
LITTLE BROTHER TRAVIS AND HER
LITTLE BROTHER SHANE.
AS THE FIRST BORN OF THE FAMILY,
HER FAMILY SAYS SHE WAS THE
ROCK.
AND IT'S DIFFICULT TO IMAGINE A
LIFE WITHOUT HER.
IT'S HARD FOR THEM, ESPECIALLY
DEVASTATING FOR THAT FAMILY.
AND IN A STATEMENT THEY SAID,
ERIN, WE ARE MOURNING HER LOSS.
SHARING OUR BEAUTIFUL MEMORIES
WE HAVE OF HER AND TRYING TO
HELP HER LITTLE BROTHER TRAVIS
UNDERSTAND WHY HE CAN'T PLAY
WITH HIS BEST FRIEND ANY MORE.
JESSICA REKOS WAS JUST SIX YEARS
OLD.
ERIN?
>> ALL RIGHT.
THANKS VERY MUCH TO YOU, NICK.
WE WANT TO LET YOU KNOW THAT WE
DO HAVE A LIVE PICTURE RIGHT NOW
OF MARIN OE ONE, THE PRESIDENT
GETTING READY TO LEAVE THE WHITE
HOUSE AND COME HERE TO NEWTOWN.
TO VISIT INDIVIDUALLY WITH THE
FAMILY AND FIRST RESPONDERS.
AND THEN HE WILL BE SPEAKING AT
A 90-MINUTE VIGIL.
NOW TO THE INVESTIGATION AND THE
LATEST THAT WE KNOW.
POLICE SAY THEY ARE CONFIDENT
THAT EVERY QUESTION INVOLVING
THE CRIME WILL BE ANSWERED.
IN PARTICULAR, THE WHY.
WE ARE FINDING OUT MORE DETAILS
ABOUT HOW THE ALLEGED GUNMAN GOT
INTO THE SCHOOL.
ALISON KOSIK JOINS US WITH THAT
INFORMATION.
WHAT'S THE LATEST THAT YOU'VE
LEARNED.
>> WHAT WE'RE LEARNING IS THE
PUSH FOR MORE INFORMATION IS
GOING ON.
AS FAR AS THE ATF GOES, THEY'RE
DONE WITH TRACING THE WEAPONS,
AS FAR AS WHO OWNS THE WEAPONS.
FEDERAL AGENTS ARE CHASING THE
LEADS, 30 GUN RANGES, 400 GUN
DEALERS.
THEY'RE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT THE GUNMAN WAS DOING IN THE
DAYS LEADING UP TO THIS
MASSACRE.
NOW I AM IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD
WHERE, WHERE, WHERE THE GUNMAN
USED TO LIVE WITH HIS MOTHER
NANCY.
WE'RE NOT YET ABLE TO CONFIRM
WHETHER OR NOT THEY'VE CLOSED.
WHETHER OR NOT AUTHORITIES HAVE
CLOSED THIS AREA AS A CRIME
SCENE.
THERE HASN'T BEEN ANY ACTIVITY
HERE SINCE EARLY AFTERNOON.
WHAT WE'RE LEARNING FROM 9
GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT, DAN
MALLOY, WE'RE LEARNING HOW LANZA
GOT INTO THE SCHOOL.
KNOWING THERE WERE SECURITY
MEASURES IN PLACE AT THE SCHOOL.
THAT YOU HAD TO BE BUZZED IN AS
OF 9:30, BUZZED INTO THE
BUILDING.
IN FACT THERE WERE SECURITY
CAMERAS YOU COULD LOOK AT THE
SECURITY CAMERA, AS TO WHO IS
LOOKING TO COME INTO THE SCHOOL.
WHAT THE GOVERNOR IS SAYING THAT
BASICALLY THIS GUNMAN BLASTED
HIS WAY IN.
HE, YOU KNOW, HE BASICALLY SHOT
AN ENTRANCE INTO THE BUILDEN.
ERIN?
>> ALL RIGHT.
ALLISON, AS YOU WERE TALKING, WE
SAW THE PRESIDENT GETTING ON TO
AIR FORCE ONE.
WE KNOW HE'S IN PROGRESS AS HE
WAVED AS HE GOT ON.
SO HE'S GOING TO BE EN ROUTE TO
NEWTOWN WHERE YOU AND I ARE.
I UNDERSTAND, ALLISON, THAT YOU
SPOKE TO A MAN WHOSE CHILDREN
USED TO GO TO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY AND HE'S TRYING TO
TAKE ACTION TO MOBILIZE HIS
NEIGHBORS.
WHAT DID HE TELL YOU HE'S DOING.
>> HIS KIDS WENT TO SANDY HOOK
YEARS AGO.
HE FEELS LIKE A LOT OF PEOPLE
FEEL IN THIS TOWN.
HOW DO YOU MAKE SENSE OF THIS?
HE SAYS SOME PEOPLE GRIEVE, WHAT
HE WANTS TO DO IS TAKE ACTION.
SO HE'S IN THE PROCESS OF
MOBILIZING PEOPLE.
HE HELD A MEETING TODAY WITH
PEOPLE TRY OG FIGURE OUT WHAT TO
DO.
AS FAR AS EMAILING THEIR
REPRESENTATIVES AND SENDING
PHONE CALLS, TRYING TO GET SOME
SORT OF ACTION ALL THE WAY UP TO
CAPITOL HILL.
THE HOPE IS TO SORT OF TRY TO
FIND SOME SORT OF SEMBLANCE OF A
REMEDY TO WHAT'S HAPPENED HERE
ON FRIDAY.
>> ALL RIGHT, ALISON KOSIK,
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> ALLISON REPORTING FOR US, AS
SHE GETS MORE INFORMATION SHE'LL
BE BACK WITH US.
WE LEARNED SOME NEW INFORMATION
ON THE TIMELINE.
A CONNECTICUT NEWSPAPER
RELEASING A CHILLING AND
EXTRELY DETAILED TIMELINE OF
WHAT HAPPENED JUST BEFORE THE
TEN MINUTES OF HORROR ON FRIDAY.
INFORMATION ABOUT THE HEROES, WE
HAVEN'T HEARD UNTIL NOW.
OH, HEY MIKE.
WHAT ARE YOU UP TO?
OH, JUST DIAGRAMMING
THIS ACCIDENT
WITH MY State Farm
POCKET AGENT APP.
YOU CAN ALSO GET A QUOTE AND PAY
YOUR PREMIUM WITH THIS THING.
I THOUGHT State Farm
DIDN'T HAVE ALL THOSE APPS?
WHERE DID YOU HEAR THAT?
THE INTERNET.
AND YOU BELIEVED IT?
YEAH. THEY CAN'T PUT ANYTHING ON
THE INTERNET THAT ISN'T TRUE.
WHERE DID YOU HEAR THAT?
[ Both ] THE INTERNET.
OH LOOK.
HERE COMES MY DATE.
I MET HIM ON THE INTERNET.
HE'S A FRENCH MODEL.
UH, BONJOUR.
[ Male Announcer ]
State Farm.
MORE MOBILE THAN EVER.
GET TO A BETTER STATE.
>>> THE HARTFORD "CURRENT"
NEWSPAPER HAS RELEASED A
CHILLING ACCOUNT OF THE SHOOTING
WITH SOME VERY HARD TO READ
DETAILS, THE ARTICLE HAS THE
HEADLINE, A METHODICAL MASSACRE,
HEART AND HEROICS, IT GOES INTO
GREAT DETAIL ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
ON FRIDAY MORNING.
I WANT TO BRING IN DAVID OWEN
NOW, HE'S BEEN REPORTING AT THE
"CURRENT" FOR 18 YEARS.
DAVID I WANT TO GO THROUGH THIS
WITH YOU WHEN I WAS READING
THIS.
ONE OF THE THINGS THAT STOOD OUT
TO ME THE MOST WAS AFTER HE
BLASTED HIS WAY INTO THE SCHOOL.
HE COULD HAVE GONE LEFT AND HE
COULD HAVE GONE RIGHT AND HE
MADE A CHOICE.
>> HE CHOSE TO GO LEFT.
TOWARDS THE CLASSROOMS.
AND WE WISH WE COULD UNDERSTAND
WHY.
WE DON'T KNOW.
>> AND THERE WERE ON THE RIGHT,
THERE WERE KIDS ALSO,
CLASSROOMS.
>> YES.
>> AUDITORIUM.
THAT WAS THE CHOICE.
>> THAT WAS THE CHOICE HE MADE,
TOWARDS THE FIRST GRADERS.
>> TELL ME ABOUT HOW HE GOT INTO
THE SCHOOL.
I KNOW THAT WE KNOW HE HAD SHOT
HIS WAY IN YOU KNOW SOME DETAILS
ABOUT HOW.
>> THERE WERE CONFLICTING
REPORTS.
BUT OUR UNDERSTANDING NOW IS
THAT HE, HE FIRED HIS WEAPON AND
MADE A HOLE IN THE GLASS
BASICALLY AND CLIMBED INTO THE
SCHOOL.
WAS NOT ALLOWED IN, FORCED HIS
WAY INTO THE SCHOOL.
>> HE FORCED HIS WAY IN.
>> TELL ME ABOUT THE FIRST
CLASSROOM THAT HE REACHED.
THAT WAS KAITLYN ROIG'S
CLASSROOM.
WE NOW KNOW ABOUT HER HEROISM.
>> THE KIDS ARE ALL HIDING,
WHICH IS SUCH A TRIBUTE TO THESE
TEACHERS.
FOR SOME REASON HE KEPT GOING
AND HE WENT TO THE SECOND
CLASSROOM, WHERE LAUREN WAS.
LAUREN ROUSSEAU, AND HER 14
KIDS.
THAT'S WHERE HE OPENED FIRE.
>> AND I KNOW SHE TRIED TO SAVE
THE CHILDREN.
SHE TRIED TO HIDE THEM.
AND SOME OF THEM FLED OUT OF
FEAR AND THAT'S WHEN HE SAW
THEM.
>> I BELIEVE THAT'S THE NEXT
CLASSROOM.
IT WAS YES, THESE TEACHERS ALL
WERE, THE EVIDENCE SHOWS JUST
HEROIC IN TERMS OF TRYING TO
PROTECT THOSE KIDS.
>> IN THE SEARCH OF HIS MOTHER'S
HOME, POLICE HAVE FOUND A LOT OF
INFORMATION.
WE DON'T YET KNOW MUCH ABOUT IT.
BUT YOU DO KNOW HOW THEY FOUND
HIS MOTHER, WHERE THEY FOUND HIS
MOTHER.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL ME?
>> WE KNOW THAT HIS MOTHER WAS
STIM IN BED.
SHE HAD BEEN SHOT TWICE IN THE
HEAD.
THAT POLICE SECURED THE HOUSE.
BEFORE THAT THEY SEARCHED IT
WITH A ROBOT OUT OF CONCERN THAT
THERE MAY HAVE BEEN BOOBY TRAPS
OR SOME OTHER DEVICE TO TRAP
POLICE.
SO THEY USED A ROBOT TO SEARCH
THE BUILDING AND THE HOUSE, AND
THAT'S BECOME RELATIVELY COMMON
PRACTICE FOR POLICE, TO INSURE
THEIR OWN SAFETY WHEN GOING INTO
A PLACE AFTER THIS EVENT.
HAD TWO BEDROOMS WHERE HE LIVED.
COMPUTERS IN ONE AND A BED IN
ANOTHER.
A HARD DRIVE HAD BEEN REMOVED
FROM A COMPUTER AND SMASHED.
WE BELIEVE THEY FOUND OTHER
RELEVANT EVIDENCE AS WELL.
>> WHAT'S YOUR UNDERSTANDING
ABOUT THEIR ABILITY TO ACCESS
THE INFORMATION ON THE HARD
DRIVE.
>> THEY'RE WORKING WITH COMPUTER
EXPERTS TO RECOVER THE DATA
THAT'S ON THAT HARD DRIVE.
>> THERE WAS ANOTHER STORY I
WANTED TO GIVE YOU A CHANCE TO
TALK ABOUT WHEN I READ YOUR
ARTICLE THAT STOOD OUT.
AND THAT WAS IN THE CLASSROOM
WHERE ONE OF THE TEACHERS HAD
TRIED TO PUT THE CHILDREN IN A
CLOSET AND HAVE THE CHILDREN BE
AS QUIET AS THEY COULD.
SOME OF THEM WERE AND SOME OF
THEM WERE CHILDREN THAT FLED.
>> TELL ME ABOUT WHAT YOU
UNDERSTAND ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
IN THAT ROOM.
>> THE TEACHER TRIED TO PROTECT
THE KIDS AGAIN.
AND HAD THEM IN A CLOSET.
TOLD THEM TO BE QUIET.
THE SOME OF THE KIDS FLED.
AND LANZA CAME IN AND HE, HE
KILLED THE TEACHER.
HE KILLED THOSE KIDS.
BUT THE OTHER KIDS STAYED QUIET
AND THEY STAYED IN THE CLOSET.
AND AFTER THE POLICE HAD, AFTER
THIS ENDED AND THE POLICE WERE
IN THERE, SEARCHING FOR THE
BUILDING, THROUGHING THROUGH
THIS HORRIBLE SITUATION.
THEY OPENED THE CLOSET AND THERE
WERE THE KIDS WHO HAD SURVIVED.
>> YOU WROTE THAT THEY OPENED
THE CLOSET AND THERE WERE SEVEN
PAIRS OF EYES STARING.
>> YES, MY COLLEAGUES REPORTED
THE BULK OF THE STORY.
THEY DID A GREAT JOB.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WE APPRECIATE YOU TAKING THE
TIME TO EXPLAIN IT TO US AND TO
EVERYONE WATCHING.
THERE'S SO MUCH HAPPENING HERE
IN NEWTOWN.
BUT WE WANT TO GO BACK TO OUR
HEADQUARTERS IN ATLANTA AND TO
DEB FERRICK, SHE HAS THE NEWS ON
WHAT WE'RE WATCHING ON THIS
SUNDAY.
>>> A DEAL COULD BE CLOSER TO
AVOID THE SO-CALLED FISCAL
CLIFF.
A SOURCE TELLS CNN THAT HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER IS OFFERING
TO INCLUDE HIGHER TAX RATES ON
PEOPLE MAKING MORE THAN $1
MILLION.
THE WHITE HOUSE IS STILL HOLDING
TO ITS $250,000 THRESHOLD.
UNLESS A DEAL IS REACHED BY
JANUARY 1st, PRACTICALLY
EVERYONE WILL BE HIT WITH A TAX
INCREASE.
>>> AND IT APPEARS THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS TAPPED
MASSACHUSETTS SENATOR, JOHN
KERRY AS HIS NEXT SECRETARY OF
STATE.
A SOURCE SAYS THE PRESIDENT MAY
MAKE THE ANNOUNCEMENT THIS WEEK.
THE 69-YEAR-OLD SENATOR NARROWLY
LOST THE PRESIDENCY IN 2004 TO
PRESIDENT GEORGE W. BUSH.
HE'S CHARGE OF THE SENATE
FOREIGN RELATIONS COMMITTEE AND
A DECORATED VETERAN OF THE
VIETNAM WAR.
AND EGYPT'S MUSLIM BROTHERHOOD
DECLARE AS NARROW VICTORY IN THE
FIRST ROUND OF HOTLY CONTESTED
CONSTITUTIONAL REFERENDUMS.
THIS SOENL THE FIRST WEEKEND OF
VOTING.
THE REST OF THE COUNTRY WILL BE
VOTING NEXT WEEKEND.
SOME CLAIMS OF VOTER
INTIMIDATION AND EARLY POLL
CLOSINGS.
THAT'S WHAT WE'VE GOT FROM HERE.
ERIN, LET'S GO BACK TO YOU IN
NEWTOWN.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH, DEB.
MANY NEWTOWN RESIDENTS ARE
SEEKING COMFORT IN FAITH.
AND JOINING ME NOW IS THE
REVEREND MARK MOORE, HE LEADS A
SMALL CONGREGATION IN NEWTOWN'S
TOWN CENTER.
NORMALLY YOUR CHURCH HAS ABOUT
20 WORSHIPPERS.
>> WE'RE A TINY LITTLE PARISH,
ONE OF TWO PARISHES DIRECTLY IN
THE VILLAGE OF SANDY HOOK.
>> WHAT WAS IT LIKE TODAY?
>> WE HAD A SERVICE YESTERDAY AT
12:00 TO ADDRESS THIS ISSUE.
IT WAS PACKED WITH PEOPLE.
AND EVEN REPORTERS FROM ALL OVER
THE WORLD WERE THERE.
AUSTRALIA, RUSSIA, ITALY,
FRANCE.
ENGLAND, GERMANY.
ALL OVER THE WORLD.
FOLLOWING THIS STORY.
ALL THE MAJOR NETWORKS WERE
THERE.
YOU KNOW, CNN WAS THERE, OF
COURSE.
AND SO THIS IS AN INTERNATIONAL
EVENT.
AND SO THE CHURCHES HAVE A
PARTICULAR ROLE WHEN SOMETHING
LIKE THIS HAPPENS.
THAT IS TO HELP PEOPLE MAKE SOME
KIND OF SENSE OF IT.
WHEN IT FIRST HAPPENED,
EVERYONE, INCLUDING ME WAS IN A
STATE OF COMPLETE SHOCK.
I HEARD, I'M THE SAME AS ANYONE
ELSE, A SENSE OF SICKENING SENSE
OF HOW COULD THIS POSSIBLY
HAPPEN.
AND YOU TRY TO WRAP YOUR MIND
AROUND IT.
AND COMPREHEND THAT YOU CAN'T,
IT'S JUST IMPOSSIBLE.
EVEN THE WAYS THAT WE TYPICALLY
TRY TO UNDERSTAND EVENTS LIKE
THIS THROUGH PSYCHOLOGY AND THEY
SAY THE MAN WAS DISTURBED AND
THINGS LIKE THAT.
HE CERTAINLY WAS.
BUT IN A WAR, YOU CAN UNDERSTAND
THE CULTURAL AND POLITICAL
TENSIONS LIKE THIS, FOR A
NATURAL DISASTER THIS GOES WAY
BEYOND THAT.
EVEN A VERY SICK MENTALLY ILL
INDIVIDUAL, COULD NEVER JUST
BECAUSE OF THAT, COMMIT A CRIME
SO HORRENDOUS.
SO YOU'RE THROWN BACK, ON
RELIGIOUS CONCEPTS, THAT'S THE
ONLY WAY TO UNDERSTAND IT.
OUR FAITH TEACHES US THERE ARE
FORCES OF GOOD AND FORCES OF
EVIL AT WORK IN A WORLD.
AND THIS WAS A TIME WHEN THE
FORCES OF EVIL WERE MANIFEST IN
A VERY DRAMATIC WAY.
>> HOW ARE YOU HELPING YOUR
PARISHIONERS?
HOW DO YOU COMFORT THEM?
IT'S ONE OF THOSE SITUATIONS
WHERE YOU WANT TO TELL PEOPLE
IT'S GOING TO BE ALL RIGHT.
BUT OF COURSE IT ISN'T GOING TO
BE ALL RIGHT.
>> OF COURSE IT ISN'T GOING TO
IT'S A DISSERVICE TO SAY
EVERYTHING IS GOING TO BE ALL
RIGHT.
I THINK THE ONE THING WE DO IS
WE DRAW PEOPLE TOGETHER SO
THERE'S A SENSE OF COMMUNITY AND
CARING.
AND THAT'S THE FIRST STAGE AND
ANY KIND OF HEALING.
BECAUSE THERE'S A TREMENDOUS
AMOUNT OF FEAR AND ANXIETY THAT
CAN ACCOMPANY THIS.
SO FACT THAT WE'RE ALL TOGETHER
IN A LOVING COMMUNITY.
IS VERY COMFORTING.
BUT BEYOND THAT, PEOPLE ASK, YOU
KNOW, TRYING TO MAKE SENSE OF
IT.
HOW CAN THIS POSSIBLY HAPPEN.
SO WE TRIED TO AT THE TIME.
REMIND THEM OF THE TEACHINGS OF
THE FAITH.
THAT THERE IS GOOD AND EVIL IN
THE WORLD.
BUT GOD IS COMPLETELY GOOD, GOD
OPPOSES EVIL AND IN THE END, GOD
IS STRONGER THAN THE FORCES OF
EVIL.
AND THE FORCES OF EVIL WOULD BE
PURGED FROM THE WORLD.
AND THAT IS OUR HOPE.
SO WE LOOK TO GOD FOR HIS, FOR
GOD'S STRENGTH, HEALING,
GUIDANCE, KNOWING THAT GOD IS
ALL-GOOD AND ALL-LOVING.
AND THAT'S A VERY POWERFUL
THING.
IF WE DON'T HAVE THAT, THEN IT'S
JUST SENSELESS MAYHEM.
AND THERE COULD BE NO HEALING
FROM THAT.
JUST THE OPPOSITE IS MORE
ALIENATION AND FEAR AND
SENSELESSNESS.
AND THAT'S SOMETHING THAT IT'S
VERY HARD TO LIVE WITH THAT KIND
OF BELIEF.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH, REVEREND
MOORE.
THERE CAN BE GREAT HOLES IN
MOMENTS LIKE THIS WHEN WE DON'T
HAVE FAITH.
AS THE REVEREND WAS SAYING,
TRYING TO UNDERSTAND HOW THIS
COULD HAPPEN IS A QUESTION FOR
PEOPLE AROUND THE WORLD.
WE WANT TO LOOK AT HOW A PERSON
COULD CARRY OUT SUCH AN EXTREME
AND UNTHINKABLE ACT OF VIOLENCE.
IT'S HARD FOR ANYONE TO FATHOM.
AS MEMORIALS ARE BEING HELD
AROUND THE NATION, OUR NEXT
GUEST WILL HELP US MAKE SENSE
OUT OF WHAT COULD LEAD A PERSON,
A HUMAN BEING, TO CARRY OUT SUCH
AN ACT OF GROSS VIOLENCE AGAINST
CHILDREN.
HOW THEY'LL LIVE TOMORROW.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
to the number 1 club
in the world.
The potential of
Manchester United unlocked.
NYSE Euronext.
Unlocking the world's potential.
have led to an increase intands
clinical depression.
Drug and alcohol abuse is up.
And those dealing with grief
don't have access to the
professional help they need.
When you see these issues, do
you want to walk away or
step up?
With a degree in the field of
Counseling or Psychology from
Capella University, you'll have
the knowledge to make
a difference in the lives of
others.
Let's get started at
CAPELLA.EDU
>>> AUTHORITIES ARE TRYING TO
GET A MORE COMPLETE PICTURE OF
THE CONNECTICUT GUNMAN.
WHAT COULD POSSIBLY TRIGGER A
HUMAN BEING TO DO WHAT THIS MAN
DID.
THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER WAS YOUNG,
HE WAS WHITE, HE WAS MALE.
TO HELP US WITH SOME ANSWERS, WE
WANT TO BRING IN JIM CLEMENTE.
HE'S A WRITER FOR THE PROGRAM,
"CRIMINAL MINDS."
WE APPRECIATE YOU TAKING TIME.
WE WERE TALKING TO THE REPORTER
FROM "HARTFORD CURRENT" WHOSE
ARTICLE WAS ENTITLED METHODICAL
WHEN HE WAS DESCRIBING THIS
CRIME.
METHODICAL IS A VERY HARD AND
AWFUL WORD TO USE WHEN TALKING
ABOUT SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
WHEN IT WAS PREPLANNED AND
PREMEDITATED.
WHAT CAN CAUSE A PERSON TO DO
THIS.
WELL.
>> WELL I THINK IN THIS CASE IT
COULD BE ANYTHING FROM
PSYCHOSIS, MENTAL ILLNESS TO A
SLOW BURN.
YOU KNOW AND A JUSTICE
COLLECTOR.
SOMEONE WHO IS HAS BUILT UP
THESE ANGERS AND RAGE OVER
YEARS.
BUT IN THIS CASE, THE MIX OF
THAT MENTAL ILLNESS OR
PSYCHOSIS, PLUS THE
SUICIDAL/HOMICIDAL IE AAL IDEAT
ACCESS TO SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPONS
WAS A RECIPE FOR DISASTER.
>> ADAM LANZA WAS NO DOUBT
TROUBLED.
I WAS AT A PIZZA PARLOR WITH
PEOPLE WHO NEW ADAM AND RYAN AND
THEIR MOTHER NANCY AND TALKED
ABOUT HIM AND SOME OF THE
TROUBLES THAT HE HAD THAT SHE
TALKED ABOUT.
HE WAS LIG WITH MISS MOTHER, HIS
FATHER WAS REMARRIED.
HIS BROTHER WAS IN NEW JERSEY.
THEY DIDN'T HAVE A LOT OF
CONTACT WITH HIM.
DO YOU THINK IS IT FAIR TO SAY
HE WAS PERHAPS INCREDIBLY
ISOLATED?
DO WE HAVE ENOUGH INFORMATION TO
KNOW THAT?
JUST IN TERMS OF INTERACTIONS
WITH OTHER PEOPLE AT ALL?
>> IT SEEMS LIKE FROM THE
REPORTS HE WAS FAIRLY ISOLATED.
EVEN IN PUBLIC HE WAS VERY
SOCIALLY INEPT AND DIDN'T
INTERACT MUCH WITH OTHER PEOPLE.
THAT ISOLATION CAN HELP MAKE
INSULAR DECISIONS AND INSULAR
UNDERSTANDINGS OF WHAT THEY'RE
GOING THROUGH.
THIS KIND OF THING IS A
COMPLICATE MIX OF BIO,
PSYCHOAND SOCIAL.
>> THE GENETICS LOADS THE GUN.
THE PSYCHOLOGY AND PERSONALITY
AIMS THE GUN AND THE EVENTS IN
THEIR LIFE PULL THE TRIGGER.
BECAUSE OF ALL OF THOSE THINGS
COMING TOGETHER, IT'S SORTS OF A
PERFECT STORM IN THIS CASE.
>> NOW, I WAS TALKING TO SOME
FRIENDS OF THE FAMILIES WERE
SAYING THIS YOUNG MAN HAD BEEN
SO INTELLIGENT HE HAD GRADUATED
HIGH SCHOOL TWO YEARS EARLY.
THIS IS WHAT THEY TOLD ME AND
THERE'S BEEN SPECULATION THAT HE
HAD ASPERGER'S SYNDROME WHICH
COMES WITH INCREDIBLY HIGH
INTELLIGENCE, FOMS OF AUTISM.
NOW SEVERAL STUDIES OF CRIMINAL
BEHAVIOR.
SHOW THAT PEOPLE WHO ARE
AUTISTIC ARE NO LORE LIKELY TO
BE CRIMINALS THAN ANYONE ELSE.
ARE WE AS PEOPLE START TO TALK
ABOUT THE IMPACTS OF THIS
DISORDER, ARE WE OFF-BASE?
I THINK FIRST OF ALL, IN MY
EXPERIENCE, I'VE BEEN INVOLVED
WITH CRIMINAL JUSTICE FOR 28
YEARS, IN MY EXPERIENCE, AUTISM
AND ASPERGER'S SYNDROME HAVE
ONLY ENTERED FREIGHT A FEW TIMES
IN THAT ENTIRE PERIOD OF TIME.
I DON'T THINK IT IS A MAJOR
CONTRIBUTING FACTOR.
OTHER THAN THE FACT THAT IT MAY
HAVE BEEN SOMETHING THAT HELPED
TO ISOLATE HIM.
HE MAY HAVE HAD PSYCHOLOGICAL
UNDIAGNOSED PSYCHOLOGICAL
PROBLEMS, MENTAL ILLNESSES.
IN FACT, SCHIZOPHRENIA MOST OF
THE TIME SHOWS UP IN LATE
ADOLESCENCE, EARLY 20s THERE ARE
THINGS THAT OBVIOUSLY COULD HAVE
HAPPENED.
THERE NEEDS TO BE MORE
INVESTIGATION INTO HIS MENTAL
STATUS.
>> SO MANY QUESTIONS UNANSWERED
TODAY, JIM, THANK YOU.
A THE NEWTOWN TRAGEDY HAS A LOT
OF PEOPLE ASKING ABOUT HOW SAFE
THEIR CHILDREN ARE AND WHAT CAN
BE DONE TO MAKE CHILDREN SAFER
AT SCHOOL.
EXPERTS SAY THAT THEY COULD GET
SOME HELP FROM THEIR CELL PHONES
THIS IS SERIOUS, WE'LL LOOK AT
THE LATEST APPS THAT ARE
DESIGNED TO HELP KEEP VERY YOUNG
CHILDREN SAFE.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
CAN YOUR MOISTURIZER DO THAT?
[ Female Announcer ]
DERMATOLOGIST RECOMMENDED
Aveeno HAS AN OAT FORMULA,
NOW PROVEN
TO BUILD A MOISTURE RESERVE,
SO SKIN CAN REPLENISH ITSELF.
THAT'S HEALTHY SKIN FOR LIFE.
ONLY FROM Aveeno.
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
PROGRESSIVE DIRECT AND OTHER
CAR INSURANCE COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
CALL OR CLICK TODAY.
WE DON'T LET FREQUENT HEARTBURN
COME BETWEEN US
AND WHAT WE LOVE.
SO IF YOU'RE ONE OF THEM PEOPLE
WHO GETS HEARTBURN
AND THEN TREATS DAY AFTER DAY...
BLOCK THE ACID WITH PRILOSEC OTC
AND DON'T GET HEARTBURN
IN THE FIRST PLACE!
[ Male Announcer ]
ONE PILL EACH MORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBURN.
>>> WE HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
A TOWN THAT IS GRIEVING.
A COUNTRY THAT GRIEVING.
FOR THE CHILDREN AND THE
TEACHERS WHO WERE KILLED HERE ON
FRIDAY MORNING.
THE STREETS HERE, THERE ARE
MEMORIALS EVERYWHERE.
YOU GET A SENSE OF HOW SMALL AND
TIGHT THIS COMMUNITY IS JUST
WALKING DOWN THE STREET AND
SINCE IT'S SORT OF LIKE A
BUCOLIC NEW ENGLAND TOWN THAT
YOU WOULD IMAGINE, YOU THINK
THERE'S NO MORE PERFECT A PLACE
THAN THIS.
CAN YOU TELL WHAT WOULD HAVE
BEEN THE PERFECT CHRISTMAS,
UNTIL THIS HORRIFIC THING
HAPPENED.
WE DO HAVE SOME NEW DETAILS
ABOUT SHOOTING AND THE
INVESTIGATION, I WANT TO SHARE
THOSE WITH YOU RIGHT NOW.
THE LATEST THAT WE HAVE.
THERE'S STILL SO MANY QUESTIONS.
WE THAT CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR,
DAN MALLOY, 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM
LANZA SHOT HIS WAY INTO THE
SCHOOL.
THERE WERE THREE GUNS FOUND NEXT
TO LANZA'S BODY.
OFFICIALS SAY ONLY ONE OF THE
GUNS WAS THE PRIMARY WEAPON AND
THAT WAS A SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE.
WE'VE LEARNED THAT THE 20
CHILDREN KILLED INSIDE THE
SCHOOL WERE SHOT MULTIPLE TIMES.
EVERY SINGLE ONE OF THOSE
CHILDREN WAS SIX OR SEVEN YEARS
OLD.
THE PRESIDENT IS COMING HERE
TONIGHT.
HE'S ON HIS WAY TO NEWTOWN RIGHT
NOW.
HE LEFT JUST ABOUT 15, 20
MINUTES AGO.
THE PRESIDENT WILL MEET WITH
FAMILIES OF 26 VICTIMS WHO WERE
KILLED IN THE MASS SHOOTING AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE SECOND DEADLIEST SHOOTING IN
AMERICAN HISTORY.
THE PRESIDENT WILL SPEAK AT AN
INTERFAITH VIGIL TONIGHT.
THE VIGIL WILL BEGIN AT 7:00
P.M. EASTERN.
WE'LL BRING IT TO YOU LIVE IN
ITS ENTIRETY.
>> THE SCHOOL SHOOTING HAS
RENEWED THE DEBATE ABOUT GUN
CONTROL ACROSS THIS COUNTRY.
A CONTENTIOUS DEBATE AT ANY
TIME.
BUT RIGHT NOW, MORE EMOTIONAL
THAN EVER BEFORE.
DEMOCRATS ARE PUSHING FOR
TIGHTER GUN LAWS.
SENATOR DIANE FEINSTEIN SAID
SHE'S GOING TO PROPOSE AN
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN WHEN THE
NEXT CONGRESS RETURNS.
HERE SHE IS.
>> THE PURPOSE OF THIS BILL IS
TO GET WHAT MAYOR BLOOMBERG
SAID, WEAPONS OF WAR OFF THE
STREETS OF OUR CITIES.
>> OF COURSE THE QUESTION IS,
WOULD BANNING GUNS STOP PEOPLE
FROM KILLING PEOPLE.
THAT'S A CENTRAL QUESTION.
BRIANNA KEILAR SHOWS US HOW THE
NEW DEBATE ON GUN PATROL IS
PUTTING NEW PRESSURE ON BARACK
OBAMA.
>> Reporter: JUST HOURS AFTER
THE CONNECTICUT SHOOTING, A
PROMISE FROM PRESIDENT OBAMA TO
TACKLE GUN VIOLENCE.
>> WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO COME
TOGETHER AND TAKE MEANINGFUL
ACTION TO PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS.
REGARDLESS OF THE POLITICS.
>> Reporter: BUT WHAT EXACTLY
DOES HE MEAN BY MEANINGFUL
ACTION?
CRITICS OF THE PRESIDENT'S
RECORD ON THE ISSUE ARE PRESSING
FOR SPECIFIC PROPOSALS.
NEW YORK MAYOR, MICHAEL
BLOOMBERG SAID CALLING FOR
MEANINGFUL ACTION IS NOT ENOUGH.
WE NEED IMMEDIATE ACTION.
WE HAVE HEARD ALL THE RHETORIC
BEFORE.
WHAT WE HAVE NOT SEEN IS
LEADERSHIP.
NOT FROM THE WHITE HOUSE, AND
NOT FROM CONGRESS.
GUN VIOLENCE HAS NOT BEEN A
PRIORITY FOR THE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION AS HE RAN FOR
PRESIDENT IN 2008, OBAMA
SUPPORTED REINSTATING A BAN ON
ASSAULT WEAPONS.
>> DON'T TELL ME WE CAN'T UPHOLD
THE SECOND AMENDMENT WHILE
KEEPING AK-47s OUT OF THE HANDS
OF CRIMINALS.
>> Reporter: ONCE AGAIN BEING HE
DID NOT MAKE GOOD ON HIS
CAMPAIGN PLEDGE.
THE BRADY COMMITTEE TO END GUN
VIOLENCE GAVE THE PRESIDENT F'S
ACROSS THE BOARD ON THE REPORT
CARD.
CONGRESS, EVEN IN THE
DEMOCRATIC-CONTROLLED SENATE,
THERE'S BEEN LITTLE APPETITE TO
TOUCH THE CONTROVERSIAL ISSUE.
MULTIPLE GUN CONTROL BILLS HAVE
BEEN INTRODUCED.
NOT A SINGLE ONE HAS MADE IT TO
THE FLOOR FOR A VOTE.
THOSE INVOLVED IN THE DEBATE
OVER GUNS SAY THE PRESIDENT HAS
A NUMBER OF OPTIONS.
REINSTATING SOME FORM OF THE
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN THAT EXPIRED
IN 1994.
BANNING HIGH-COUNT MAGAZINES, OR
IMPROVING THE REPORTING OF
PEOPLE WITH MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES
TO MAKE SURE THEY'RE
DISQUALIFIED FROM PURCHASING
FIREARMS.
POLLS SHOW AMERICANS HAVE BECOME
ACCUSTOMED TO DAILY REPORTS OF
GUN DEATHS.
FRIDAY MORNING, A SHOOTER KILLED
A MEMPHIS POLICE OFFICER WHO WAS
A MOTHER OF FOUR.
FRIDAY NIGHT, A MAN SHOT AND
KILLED A WOMAN WORKING AT A LAS
VEGAS HOTEL, BEFORE KILLING
HIMSELF.
EARLY SATURDAY MORNING, IN
BIRMINGHAM, ALABAMA, POLICE
KILLED A GUNMAN INSIDE A
HOSPITAL WHERE THREE PEOPLE WERE
HURT.
BUT NEW YORK CONGRESSWOMAN,
CAROLYN McCARTHY, WHOSE HUSBAND
DIED AND SON WAS INJURED WHEN A
SHOOTER OPENED FIRE ON A LONG
ISLAND TRAIN IN 1993, SAYS THE
CONNECTICUT SHOOTING MAY BE WHAT
FORCES PRESIDENT OBAMA AND
CONGRESS, TO FINALLY ADDRESS THE
PROBLEM.
>> LET'S FACE IT.
WE NEED TO HAVE THE PRESIDENT AS
THE BULLY PULPIT.
ON TRYING TO GET SOMETHING DONE.
THIS TIME WHAT I SAW WAS
DIFFERENT, THAT POLITICIANS THAT
USUALLY DON'T TALK ABOUT IT,
WERE TALKING ABOUT IT.
SO THERE IS A DIFFERENCE THIS
TIME AROUND.
THERE IS A DIFFERENCE MAYBE THE
PENDULUM IS TURNING AND THE
COUNTRY IS READY TO GET SERIOUS
ABOUT THIS ISSUE.
>> WHITE HOUSE SPOKESMAN JAY
CARNEY SAID FRIDAY, IT'S THE
TIME TO EXPRESS SYMPATHY FOR
VICTIMS' FAMILIES.
NOT THE TIME TO ENGAGE IN A
POLICY DEBATE.
BUT I SPOKE WITH CONGRESSWOMAN
McCARTHY AND SHE SAID SHE CALLED
UP THE WHITE HOUSE AND SAID,
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
THIS IS SOMETHING THAT WE SHOULD
HAVE BEEN DISCUSSING FOR YEARS.
BRIANNA KEILAR, CNN, THE WHITE
HOUSE.
>>> THERE'S A LOT HAPPENING HERE
IN NEWTOWN THIS AFTERNOON.
WE WANT TO GO BACK TO CNN WORLD
HEADQUARTERS IN ATLANTA TO
UPDATE YOU ON THE OTHER KEY
STORIES WE'RE WATCHING THIS
AFTERNOON.
DEB?
>>> WELL IN CALIFORNIA, A VERY
FRIGHTENING INCIDENT FOR
SHOPPERS AT A MALL PARKING LOT
IN NEWPORT BEACH.
[ GUNSHOTS ]
>> THAT IS THE SOUND OF GUNFIRE.
A MAN IN THE PARKING LOT FIRES
50 SHOTS IN THE AIR YESTERDAY.
STORES WERE FILLED WITH
SHOPPERS.
AND THOSE STORES QUICKLY LOCKED
THEIR DOORS.
NO ONE WAS HIT, BUT ONE PERSON
SUFFERED MINOR INJURIES TRYING
TO GET OUT OF THE AREA.
THE SUSPECT IS IN CUSTODY.
POLICE HAVE NOT GIVEN A REASON
FOR THE SHOOTING.
>>> AND TOMORROW, THE STATE
DEPARTMENT HANDS OVER A DETAILED
REPORT TO CONGRESS ON THE ATTACK
ON THE CONSULATE IN BENGHAZI,
LIBYA.
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON ORDERED THE REVIEW.
IT PRECEDES A CLASSIFIED
BRIEFING FOR CONGRESS ON
WEDNESDAY.
SECRETARY CLINTON WILL NOT
TESTIFY, SHE SUFFERED A
CONCUSSION AFTER A FALL
YESTERDAY.
>>> AND IN LONDON, THE DUCHESS
OF CAMBRIDGE ATTENDS HER FIRST
PUBLIC ENGAGEMENT SINCE HER
PREGNANCY WAS ANNOUNCED THIS
MONTH.
A SPOKESMAN SAYS KATHERINE IS
APPEARING AT BBC SPORTS
PERSONALITY OF THE YEAR AWARDS
TONIGHT.
SHE WAS LAST SEEN DECEMBER 6th,
LEAVING THE HOSPITAL AFTER
SEVERAL DAYS OF TREATMENT FOR
ACUTE MORNING SICKNESS.
>>> WELL PHONES AND MOBILE
DEVICES MAY NOT BE ABLE TO
PREVENT WHAT HAPPENED IN
NEWTOWN.
BUT THEY CAN BE USED TO HELP
KEEP KIDS SAFE AND LET PARENTS
KNOW WHEN THINGS GO WRONG.
OUR TECHNOLOGY REPORTER, LORI
SIEGEL JOINING US NOW.
LORI, WITH THE CELL PHONE, KIDS
CAN AT LEAST CALL 911 OR THEIR
PARENTS, LET THEM KNOW THAT
THEY'RE OKAY.
IF THEY FIND THEMSELVES IN
SITUATIONS LIKE WHAT HAPPENED IN
NEWTOWN.
>> IN THESE SITUATIONS, THEY'RE
HORRIFIC AND TECHNOLOGY CAN'T
STOP THIS KIND OF THING FROM
HAPPENING.
THAT BEING SAID, IT CAN HELP US
CONNECT A LOT BETTER IN TIMES OF
TRAGEDY AND EMERGENCY
SITUATIONS.
LET ME TELL YOU ABOUT AN APP
CALLED CRIME PUSH.
ESSENTIALLY A GROUP OF
ENTREPRENEURIN
ENTREPRENEURS, HAVE CONTACTED
LOCAL AUTHORITIES AND SCHOOL
DISTRICTS, CREATING AN APP TO
HELP YOU BETTER CONNECT IF
SOMETHING LIKE THIS HAPPENS.
I WANT TO TAKE YOU THROUGH
EXACTLY HOW IT WORKS.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT RIGHT THERE.
ESSENTIALLY IT'S AN APP THAT
AGGREGATES EMERGENCY SCHOOL
CONTACTS.
CAN YOU PING STUDENTS WITH
RELEVANT UPDATES.
STUDENTS WOULD HAVE GOTTEN A
PUSH NOTIFICATION SAYING THERE'S
A SHOOTER HERE.
AND THE NEXT POINT IS IT WILL
SEND YOU INTO AN ACTIVE SAFETY
SHELTER.
IT WILL SEND YOU A PUSH
NOTIFICATION SAYING HEY, THE GYM
IS SAFE, TRY TO GET THERE.
AND THEY CAN TEXT LAW
ENFORCEMENT YOUR GPS
COORDINATES.
TIMES LIKE THESE YOU MIGHT NOT
BE ABLE TO PICK UP THE PHONE,
CALL LAW ENFORCEMENT, THIS
ENABLES YOU TO TEXT LOCAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT.
SHAKE YOUR PHONE AND CALL 911.
IT CAN BE USED FOR COLLECTING
EVIDENCE, TAKING PICTURES, SEND
THEM TO LOCAL LAW ENFORCEMENT.
>> PARENTS WANT TO KNOW WHERE
THEIR CHILDREN ARE IN AN
EMERGENCY AND MAKE SURE THAT
KIDS ARE GOING IN THE RIGHT
DIRECTION IT MAY BE MORE
CHALLENGING FOR THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL KIDS THAT WE SAW
OBVIOUSLY.
BUT FOR HIGH SCHOOL KIDS WHO
ALWAYS HAVE CELL PHONES THAT
COULD BE HELPFUL.
WHAT ABOUT BETTER WAYS TO
CONNECT WITH YOUR KIDS?
THE ONE THING YOU WANT IS YOU
WANT TO BE ABLE TO SAY OKAY,
WHERE ARE YOU?
HOW DO WE GET TO HELP OR EVEN
GIVE THEM INFORMATION.
>> YOU TELL YOUR KIDS, IF
THERE'S AN EMERGENCY, CALL ME.
BUT WHAT HAPPENS IF YOU DON'T,
YOU'RE NOT BY THE PHONE.
THERE'S AN APP CALLED NEAR
PARENT.
NEAR PARENT ESSENTIALLY ALLOWS
YOU TO CONNECT BETTER WITH YOUR
KIDS.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT FEATURES, LOOK
AT THE CHECK-IN, SMALL ALERT,
BIG ALERT.
ALL FOR YOUR KIDS TO CONNECT
WITH YOU.
ESSENTIALLY NEAR PARENT ALLOWS
YOU TO CREATE A GPS-ENABLED SAFE
ZONE ALERT FOR YOUR CHILD.
THAT MEANS YOU'LL GET A PUSH
NOTIFICATION IF YOUR CHILD GOES
AWAY FROM THE SCHOOL OR
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
SOME PEOPLE CALL IT OVERBEARING,
YOU LOOK AT WHAT'S HAPPENED IN
THE LAST COUPLE OF DAYS AND YOU
THINK TWICE.
IT ALLOWS A CHILD TO SEND HELP
ALERTS TO MULTIPLE COMMUNITY
MEMBERS.
YOU SAW EARLIER, YOU CAN PRESS
ONE BUTTON AND A PUSH
NOTIFICATION GOES OUT TO
MULTIPLE ADULTS.
THIS CAN BE USED BEYOND A TRAGIC
EVENT IN OUR EMERGENCY.
BUT JUST IN NORMAL PARENTING.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
WITH KIDS RIGHT NOW.
ESPECIALLY WHEN THEY'RE WALKING
AROUND IN THEIR TOWN OR CITY,
YOU WANT TO BE ABLE TO TRACK
THEM.
LORI SIEGEL, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
THIS IS REALLY HELPFUL AND A LOT
OF PARENTS HOPING TO KEEP THEIR
KIDS AS SAFE AS POSSIBLE.
KNOW WHERE THEY ARE SO THEY CAN
FIND THEM WHEN THEY NEED.
QUITE FRANKLY, THERE'S NO WAY TO
EXPLAIN HOW YOU DEAL WITH THE
PAIN OF LOSING A CHILD IN A
MASSACRE.
BUT ONE FATHER IS BRAVELY
TELLING THE STORY OF HIS
6-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER AND HOPING
TO BEGIN THE HEALING PROCESS,
YOU WILL HEAR HIS POWERFUL
WORDS, NEXT.
THIS IS AMERICA.
WE DON'T LET FREQUENT HEARTBURN
COME BETWEEN US
AND WHAT WE LOVE.
SO IF YOU'RE ONE OF THEM PEOPLE
WHO GETS HEARTBURN
AND THEN TREATS DAY AFTER DAY...
BLOCK THE ACID WITH PRILOSEC OTC
AND DON'T GET HEARTBURN
IN THE FIRST PLACE!
[ Male Announcer ]
ONE PILL EACH MORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBURN.
>>> THE LIVES OF SO MANY
FAMILIES IN NEWTOWN HAVE BEEN
RIPPED APART.
AND WILL NEVER, EVER BE THE SAME
AGAIN.
NO ONE CAN EVER THINK OR IMAGINE
OF SENDING A CHILD OFF TO SCHOOL
WHETHER THEY'RE EXCITED OR
CRYING TO LEAVE YOU.
NOT SEEING THAT CHILD EVER
AGAIN.
AS KEUNG LAW, ONE FAMILY IS
SPEAKING OUT ABOUT HOW HE AND
HIS FAMILY ARE TRYING TO FIND
PEACE NOW.
>> I DON'T KNOW HOW TO GET
THROUGH SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
MY WIFE AND I DON'T UNDERSTAND
HOW TO PROCESS ALL OF THIS.
>> HOW CAN YOU, ASKS ROBBIE
PARKER, WHEN YOU LOSE YOUR
6-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER.
EMILIE, HIS BRIGHT LIGHT.
ARTIST WITH CRAYONS, ELDER
SISTER TO A 3-YEAR-OLD AND
4-YEAR-OLD.
>> SHE WAS THE TYPE OF PERSON
THAT COULD JUST LIGHT UP A ROOM.
SHE -- SHE ALWAYS HAD SOMETHING
KIND TO SAY ABOUT ANYBODY.
AND HER, HER LOVE AND THE
STRENGTH THAT SHE GAVE US AND
THE EXAMPLE THAT SHE SHOWED US
ARE IS REMARKABLE.
SHE IS AN INCREDIBLE PERSON.
AND I'M SO BLESSED TO BE HER
DAD.
>> WE'RE JUST DEVASTATED THAT
SOMEONE SO BEAUTIFUL AND PERFECT
IS NO LONGER GOING TO BE IN OUR
LIVES.
AND FOR NO REASON.
>> BUT THEN, JUST A DAY AFTER
LOSING THIS LITTLE GIRL TO
VIOLENCE, HER 30-YEAR-OLD FATHER
SAID VERY SIMPLY, I AM NOT
ANGRY.
>> AS WE MOVE ON FROM WHAT
HAPPENED HERE, WHAT HAPPENED TO
SO MANY PEOPLE, LET IT NOT TURN
INTO SOMETHING THAT DEFINES US.
BUT SOMETHING THAT INSPIRES US
TO BE BETTER, TO BE MORE
COMPASSIONATE, AND MORE HUMBLE
PEOPLE.
THE BEST THING THAT I CAN THINK
OF TO DO TO MOVE ON IS TO HELP
OTHER PEOPLE.
WHEN YOU HELP OTHER PEOPLE, YOU
FEEL BETTER ABOUT YOURSELF.
AND THE MORE PEOPLE HELP OTHER
PEOPLE, THEN THE MORE PEOPLE ARE
BLESSED.
>> THE FAMILY MOVED TO NEWTOWN,
FROM SALT LAKE JUST EIGHT MONTHS
AGO, BECAUSE EMILIEMILIE'S FATHT
A JOB AT THE LOCAL HOSPITAL
WHERE HE CARES FOR NEWBORNS.
BRENT KELLER IS THE FAMILY'S
BISHOP.
>> I DON'T KNOW HOW THEY ARE
COPING AND DEALING AS WELL AS
THEY ARE THEY ARE TRULY STRONG
AND FAITHFUL PEOPLE.
I THINK THEIR FOCUS ON FAMILY
AND THE IMPORTANCE OF FAMILY IN
THEIR LIFE IS REALLY WHAT IS
SUSTAINING THEM AND HELPING THEM
RIGHT NOW.
>> YOU CAN NEVER STOP BEING THE
BEST PARENT THAT YOU CAN BE.
YOU CAN ALWAYS BE BETTER, YOU
CAN ALWAYS BE MORE PATIENT, YOU
CAN ALWAYS BE MORE LOVING AND
UNDERSTANDING AND WILLING TO
ACCEPT YOUR CHILDREN FOR WHO
THEY ARE.
I REALLY HOPE THAT AS I CONTINUE
TO BE A DAD TO MY TWO CHILDREN
THAT I CAN JUST, IF ANYBODY
LOOKS BACK ON MY LIFE, THE
NUMBER ONE THING THEY CAN SAY
ABOUT ME IS THAT I WAS A GREAT
DAD.
>> KEUNG LAW, CNN, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> I WANT TO BRING IN CLINICAL
PSYCHOLOGI
PSYCHOLOGIST.
DR. JEFF GUARDIER.
WE'RE LISTENING TO ROBBIE
PARKER, SAYING THINGS THAT I
KNOW FOR MANY PEOPLE WATCHING,
IT'S HARD TO IMAGINE THE
BRAVELY.
WHEN HE SAYS I'M NOT ANGRY, I
DON'T WANT THIS TO BE SOMETHING
THAT DEFINES ME, I WANT IT TO
INSPIRE ME TO BE BETTER.
A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE FEELING
ANGRY, VERY, VERY ANGRY.
HOW CAN THEY BEGIN TO GET THEIR
ARMS AROUND WHAT HAS HAPPENED TO
THEIR CHILDREN.
>>> I THINK WHAT THEY NEED TO
LOOK AT, ERIN IS WHAT ROBBIE
PARKER IS DOING RIGHT NOW, HE'S
BEING BRAVE, HE'S BEING A ROLE
MODEL.
HE'S USING WHAT WE SEE IN
PSYCHOLOGY AS THE HEALTHIEST WAY
TO COPE WITH THE TRAGEDY.
HE'S COMMUNICATING ABOUT IT.
SECONDLY, HE IS OPENLY GRIEVING
AND NOT IN DENIAL AS SOME PEOPLE
MIGHT STILL BE.
THIRD, HE'S LOOKING AT WHAT IS
MOST POSITIVE ABOUT HIS
DAUGHTER.
THE FACT THAT HE WAS BLESSED,
THAT SHE HAD SOME TIME ON THIS
EARTH.
AND HE IS CELEBRATING THAT AND
THAT IS IMPORTANT.
WE'RE ALSO LOOKING AT THE FACT
THAT HE'S USING SPIRITSPIRITUAL.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO BELIEVE IN A
GOD, BUT THERE IS SPIRITUALITY,
A HIGHER POWER THAT WE GIVE THAT
PAIN OVER TO, BECAUSE WE CAN'T
HAND IT WILL AS INDIVIDUALS AND
PSYCHOLOGY MAY NOT HAVE THE
ANSWER.
>> DR. GUARDIER, WHAT DOES THE
TOWN DO, SUCH A SMALL AND
INTIMATE TOWN.
AND THIS -- ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
WAS SUCH, IT WAS A PART OF THE
COMMUNITY.
IT'S GOING TO BE THERE, IT'S A
CONSTANT SORE AND A HORRIBLE
REMINDER FOR PEOPLE.
SO, DO YOU GET RID OF THE
SCHOOL?
DO YOU NEVER HAVE PEOPLE GO
BACK?
DO YOU DEMOLISH IT?
HA DO YOU DO?
>> I THINK THE MOST IMPORTANT
THING THAT WE CAN DO, AGAIN FROM
WHAT ROBBIE PARKER HAS DONE, THE
IDEA OF TAKING THIS TRAGEDY AND
COMING OUT OF IT, NOT JUST AS A
SURVIVOR, NOT JUST AS A VICTIM,
BUT REALLY AS A VICTOR.
WHAT CAN WE LEARN FROM THIS.
AND HOW DO WE MOVE ON?
HOW DO WE CELEBRATE LIFE FROM
THIS KIND OF AWFUL TRAGEDY.
WITH THE SCHOOL AND I TALKED
ABOUT THIS EARLIER, NO, WE DON'T
TEAR IT DOWN, THEY MAY LOOK AT
PERHAPS DOING SOMETHING,
CHANGING THOSE CLASSROOMS,
MAKING THEM MORE FORTIFIED OR
CHANGING THEM FROM CLASSROOMS TO
ANOTHER KIND OF A PURPOSE FOR A
ROOM, BECAUSE OF THOSE HORRIBLE
MEMORIES.
BUT WE HAVE TO BRING CHILDREN
BACK TO THE SCHOOL BECAUSE WE
DON'T WANT THEM TO DEVELOP A
PHOBIA AROUND SCHOOLS, OR AROUND
THEIR PARTICULAR SCHOOL.
>> I'M SORRY TO INTERRUPT YOU,
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WE HAVE A PRESS CONFERENCE GOING
ON WITH THE LATEST THAT THE
POLICE KNOW.
>> THE LAST TWO DECEASED, THE
FEMALE THAT WAS FOUND IN THE
SECONDARY SCENE LOCATION LOCATI
YOGANADA STREET.
THE DEATH HAS BEEN RULED A
HOMICIDE.
THE MALE SUSPECT IDENTIFIED AS
THE SHOOTER AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HAS BEEN
POSITIVELY IDENTIFIED AS ADAM
LAN
LANZA.
HIS CAUSE WAS GUNSHOT WOUND AND
HIS DEATH HAS BEEN RULED A
SUICIDE.
THERE HAVE BEEN YES'S ABOUT THE
WEAPONRY AND I WOULD LIKE TO
TAKE A MINUTE TO DISCUSS WITH
YOU BRIEFLY, VERY SUPER
FISHESLY, SOME OF THE
INFORMATION THAT CAN BE RELEASED
AT THIS TIME.
THE WEAPON THAT WAS UTILIZED
MOST OF THE TIME DURING THIS
HORRIFIC CRIME WAS IDENTIFIED AS
A BUSH MASTER AR-15 ASSAULT-TYPE
WEAP
WEAPON.
IT HAD HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINES
INCHES ADDITION TO THAT THE
SUBJECT HAD IN HIS POSSESSION A
IS GLOCK, AND BOTH HAD
ADDITIONAL MAGAZINES AND
AMMUNITION.
THE FOURTH WEAPON WAS A SHOTGUN
RECOVERED FROM THE SUSPECT'S
VEHICLE PARKED OUTSIDE OF THE
SCHOOL.
THAT WEAPONRY THAT IS GOING, AS
I SAID, GOING TO BE COMPLETELY
EXAMINED IN THE FORENSIC
LABORATORY.
IT'S GOING TO BE HISTORICALLY
SEARCHED SO WE CAN ATTEMPT TO
DETERMINE EVERY PATH THAT THOSE
WEAPONS TOOK SINCE THEY WERE
MANUFACTURED, EVERY TIME THAT
THEY WERE USED, AS MUCH
INFORMATION AS POSSIBLE THAT WE
CAN OBTAIN RELATIVE TO EACH AND
EVERY WEAPON.
THE LAST THING, I WOULD LIKE TO
RESTATE WHAT WE STATED THIS
MORNING, ABOUT ANYONE THAT
HARASSES, THREATENS OR
INTIMIDATES OR INTERFERES WITH
THE INVESTIGATION, UTILIZING ANY
SOCIAL MEDIA WILL BE PROSECUTED
TO THE FULLEST EXTENT OF THE
LAW.
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT HARASSMENT
INCLUDES IN-PERSON CONTACT BUT
ALSO CONTACT ON THE INTERNET,
SOCIAL MEDIA, TELEPHONE, ANY
OTHER MEANS OF COMMUNICATION.
WE AGAIN ARE ASKING AND
IMPLORING MEMBERS OF THE MEDIA
TO PLEASE RESPECT THE FAMILY'S
PRIVACIES.
WE ARE CONTINUING TO STAFF A
TROOPER AS A CONDUIT OR A LINE
OF COMMUNICATION TO ASSIST THE
FAMILIES, ALL 26 FAMILIES IN
THIS INCIDENT AND WILL DO SO PER
THE COLONEL OF STATE POLICE
INDEFINITELY.
I WILL TAKE A COUPLE OF
QUESTIONS.
AGAIN, UNDERSTANDING THAT THERE
ARE CERTAIN THINGS THAT WE STILL
CANNOT ANSWER AND CANNOT
DISCUSS.
>> [ INAUDIBLE ]
>> THERE WAS, IN FACT, A THREAT
AT THE ST. ROSE CHURCH HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
THE CHURCH, EVERYTHING IS TAKEN
EXTREMELY SERIOUSLY.
THE CHURCH WAS EVACUATED AS A
PRECAUTION.
IT WAS THOROUGHLY SEARCHED, AS
WAS THE RECTORY AND WE HAVE
INITIATED A CRIMINAL
INVESTIGATION, WORKING WITH
NEWTON POLICE IN THIS PARTICULAR
INCIDENT.
I HAVE NO FURTHER DETAILS.
I DO NOT KNOW THE CONTENT OF THE
THREAT.
BUT SUFFICE IT TO SAY WE TREAT
THESE KIND OF INSTANCES AS
SERIOUS CRIMES, THEY ARE
INVESTIGATED AS SUCH.
IF THE PERPETRATOR OF THAT IS
IDENTIFIED THAT INDIVIDUAL WILL
BE PROSECUTED TO THE FULLEST
EXTENT OF THE LAW.
>> IT WAS PHONED IN?
CAN YOU TELL US THAT?
>> WHO DID THE PHONE CALL COME
TO?
>> THAT IS AS MUCH INFORMATION I
HAVE ON T.
>> WAS IT A PHONE CALL?
CAN YOU TELL US THAT?
>> YES.
>> LIEUTENANT, YOU TALK ABOUT
THE BUSHMASTER WAS USED MOST OF
THE TIME.
CAN YOU GIVE ANY DETAILS AS TO,
FIRST OF ALL, WHAT BEN UPON
NANCY LANZA WAS SHOT WITH AND
SECOND OF ALL, DID HE USE THE
HAND GUNS AT ALL AT THE SCHOOL?
>> DIE NOT NOTE WEAPON NANCY LAN
ZA WAS SHOT W I SIMPLY DON'T
KNOW THAT THE BUSH MASTER WAS
USED, AS WAS EXPLAINED
YESTERDAY, IN THE SCHOOL, IN ITS
ENTIRETY AND THE HANDGUN WAS
USED TO TAKE HIS OWN LIFE.
>> CAN YOU TELL ME ABOUT THE
BULLETS FIRED FROM THE
BUSHMASTER, ANY RICOCHET OUT OF
THEM?
>> A TRAJECTORY OF THE SHOTS AND
ALL THE AMMUNITION USED IN THIS
HORRIFIC CRIME WILL BE EXAM MIND
THOROUGHLY REPORTED IN THE
REPORT.
I DON'T HAVE THAT INFORMATION.
>> [ INAUDIBLE ]
>> A RIFLE OR ALSO FOR THE --
>> HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINE FOR
THE RIFLE AND MULTIPLE MAGAZINES
FOR THE RIFLE AND MULTIPLE
MAGAZINES FOR BOTH HAND GUNS.
>> LIEUTENANT, IS THERE
[ INAUDIBLE ].
>> I DON'T WANT TO STATE THAT
I'M SURE THEY DID EVERYTHING
THEY COULD I DON'T WANT TO GET
INTO THAT SPECIFIC DETAIL AT
THAT TIME.
>> [ INAUDIBLE ]
>> MOTIVE, AS I DISCUSSED
EARLIER, THAT WILL COME AS WE
FINISH THE INVESTIGATION.
WE SIMPLY CAN'T PIECEMEAL IT.
WE DON'T HAVE A SPECIFIC REASON
WE CAN STAND HERE AND SAY THIS
OCCURRED.
WE WILL AND WE ARE SEARCHING
DILIGENTLY AND NON-STOP TO
ATTEMPT TO ANSWER THAT QUESTION.
>> DID THE SHOOTER TAKE HIS OWN
LIFE AS POLICE WERE COMING --
>> THE TIMELINE IS BEING
ESTABLISHED BY INVESTIGATORS,
THE BEST I CAN DO WITH THAT.
>> MAY WE ASK A POINT OF
CLARIFICATION?
>> YOU CAN, SIR.
>> TALK ABOUT THE --
[ INAUDIBLE ] NEWTOWN SCHOOLS
REMAIN CLOSED [ INAUDIBLE ].
>> YEAH GO AHEAD.
>> WE ARE STILL WORKING WITH THE
SUPERINTENDENT OF SCHOOLS TO DO
WHAT'S BEST OBVIOUSLY, IT'S AN
EMOTIONAL TIME.
THE PLAN IS STILL UP IN THE AIR,
FINALIZING THE PLANS AND GET
THAT INFORMATION OUT TO YOU AS
SOON AS POSSIBLE.
>> SAFE TO SAY THE NEWTOWN
SCHOOLS WILL REMAIN CLOSED FOR
THIS WEEK?
>> AS I SAID IT IS STILL TO BE
DETERMINED.
YEAH.
>> DO WE KNOW HOW MANY SHOTS
WERE FIRED YET?
>> THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO SAY.
WE DO KNOW HOW MANY ROUNDS WE
RECOVERED DORK KNOW HOW MANY
SHELL CASINGS RECOVERED, I DON'T
HAVE THAT INFORMATION TO GIVE
OUT PUBLICLY JUST YET.
I WOULD BE SPECULATING AND
GUESSING.
>> HOW MANY MAGAZINES WERE
EMPTY?
>> NUMEROUS -- AGAIN, THAT'S ALL
INVESTIGATORY INFORMATION THAT
I'M NOT PRIVY TO.
I SIMPLY DON'T HAVE THAT TO GIVE
YOU.
>> MANY.
MANY.
HUNDREDS.
>> [ INAUDIBLE ]
>> CORRECT.
CORRECT.
SIR?
>> [ INAUDIBLE ].
>> I DON'T KNOW THAT.
I DON'T KNOW THAT.
>> [ INAUDIBLE ].
>> NO THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES IS ATTENDING A
MEMORIAL SERVICE TONIGHT AND HE
IS COMING TO THE TOWN OF
NEWTOWN.
>> WHAT IS THE SECURITY AND
ACCESS LIKE FOR THAT?
[ INAUDIBLE ]
>> YEAH THE AGAIN, WE DON'T
DISCUSS THE SECURITY FOUR THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES.
SUFFICE IT TO SAY THAT
SIGNIFICANT SECURITY WILL BE IN
PLACE AS IS ALWAYS THE CASE WHEN
THE PRESIDENT MAKES A VISIT
ANYWHERE.
>> A TIMEFRAME FOR MS. LANZA'S
DEATH BEEN ESTABLISHED?
>> NO, SIR.
NO, SIR.
>> NO TIME AT ALL?
>> NO TIMEFRAME HAS BEEN
DETERMINED.
>> WHO'S INVITED TO THE
MEMORIAL?
>> YES, SIR.
>> ARE YOU MAKING PROGRESS YOU
FEEL IN DETERMINING THE MOTIVE?
>> CERTAINLY, WE ARE PLEASED
WITH THE WORK THAT'S BEEN DONE
SO FAR.
HOPEFULLY THAT HELPS ANSWER THAT
QUESTION.
WE ARE PLEASED WITH THE PROGRESS
THAT WE ARE MAKING.
THIS IS A VERY LONG, TEDIOUS
PROCESS, WHICH I'VE STATED.
IT'S GOING TO TAKE MANY, MANY
MAN HOURS, OKAY, TO ATTEMPT TO
DRAW THIS PICTURE TOGETHER, TO
PUT THIS PUZZLE TOGETHER.
THE MINUTE WE HAVE IT, OUR
OBJECTIVE HERE IS TO MAKE SURE
YOU, YOU BE THE MEMBERS OF THE
PUBLIC, RECEIVE THAT INFORMATION
AS QUICKLY AND OFFICIALLY AS
POSSIBLE.
TO STATE RIGHT NOW WE HAVE A
MOTIVE, WE HAVE A MOTIVE WE ARE
PREPARED TO DISCUSS PUBLICLY, IT
JUST CANNOT HAPPEN DO NOT HAVE
THAT INFORMATION.
>> ANY DETAIL ABOUT THE TEACHER
WHO SAVED THE CHILDREN BY
PUTTING YOU THE CHILDREN INTO A
CLOSET?
>> AGAIN, I DON'T WANT TO SCUM
THE CRIME SCENE AT ALL.
>> [ INAUDIBLE ].
>> WE DID SEIZE A GREAT DEAL OF
EVIDENCE, OUR DETECTIVES
EXECUTED NUMEROUS WARRANTS IN
THIS CASE
WE DO NOT DETAIL THE CONTENT OF
WHAT WE SEIZE IN ANY CRIMINAL
INVESTIGATION.
I CAN TELL THAT YOU WE WERE
SUCCESSFUL IN SEIZING A GREAT
DEAL OF EVIDENCE IN THIS
INVESTIGATION.
ALL THAT EVIDENCE, EVERY STITCH
OF IT NEEDS TO BE ANALYZED AND
IT WILL BE, WHETHER IT'S AT OUR
FORENSIC LABORATORY OR BY
SPECIALISTS WITHIN OUR
DEPARTMENT OR OTHER DEPARTMENTS,
AS TIME GOES ON.
WE ANTICIPATE THIS IS GOING TO
BE THE LAST DISCUSSION TODAY.
WITH THE PRESIDENT COMING IN, WE
HAVE A DEAL ON OUR PLATE.
IF ANYTHING ADDITIONAL SHOULD
SURFACE BETWEEN NOW AND TOMORROW
MORNING, OKAY, WE WILL POST IT
ON OUR WEBSITE YOU ON THE STATE
POLICE WEBSITE BUT WE DO NOT
ANTICIPATE ANYTHING OF A PUBLIC
NATURE TO ARRIVE.
SHOULD IT ARISE I SUGGEST CHECK
OUR WEBSITE ON A REGULAR BASIS.
WE WILL COME BACK TOMORROW
MORNING, WE WILL BE HERE BY,
SHOOT FOR 9:00, WE WANT TO KEEP
YOU UPDATED AS MUCH AS WE