AND MAKE OUR COUNTRY WORTHY OF
THEIR MEMORY.
>> "OUTFRONT" NEXT, HONORING THE
HEROES OF THE NEWTOWN SCHOOL
SHOOTING AND REMEMBERING LOVED
ONES TAKEN TOO EARLY.
AND WE HAVE THE LATEST ON THE
INVESTIGATION, TRYING TO FIND
ANSWERS TO THE BIGGEST QUESTION,
WHY.
AND A BLOGGER WRITES A PIECE
THAT WAS ENTITLED I'M ADAM
LANZA'SMOTOR.
SHE IGNITED A FIRE STORM.
THAT MOM ANSWERS CRITICS
TONIGHT.
LET'S GO "OUTFRONT."
>>> GOOD EVENING, EVERYONE.
I'M ERIN BURNETT, "OUTFRONT"
TONIGHT, HONORING THE DEAD.
THE GRIEVING COMMUNITY OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, BEGAN THE
BURIALS TODAY.
JUST A MOMENT AGO, WE WERE
APPROACHED BY A REPRESENTATIVE
FOR MADELEINE HUH SHOE.
HER FAMILY WANTED US TO KNOW --
I'M GOING TO QUOTE THE WORDS
THEY SAID WITH ALL OF YOU,
SWEET, UNIQUE, BRIGHT,
SPARKLING, DETERMINED LITTLE
GIRL.
SHE WAS AN AVID READER WHO LOVED
RUNNING AND DANCING.
SHE WAS A BORN LEADER.
THIS IS THE START OF WHAT WILL
BE A PAINFUL WEEK AS FRIENDS AND
FAMILY TRY TO PREPARE TO TRY TO
SAY GOOD-BYE TO THE 20 CHILDREN
AND SIX EDUCATORS WHO WERE
KILLED ON FRIDAY IN THE SECOND
WORST SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
AMERICAN HISTORY.
AS NEWTOWN MOURNS, INVESTIGATORS
ARE STILL TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT MOTIVATED ADAM LANZA TO GO
ON A SHOOTING SPREE, TO KILL
CHILDREN, AND ALSO TAKE THE LIFE
OF HIS OWN MOTHER.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE MORE ON THE
INVESTIGATION IN A MOMENT.
BUT THE TRUTH IS, WE MAY NEVER
KNOW WHY ADAM LANZA CHOSE TO GO
ON A MASS KILLING SPREE.
WE MAY NEVER KNOW WHY HE CHOSE
TO GO IN A SCHOOL AND KILL
INNOCENT 6 AND 7-YEAR-OLDS, BUT
WE'RE LEARN AGLOT MORE TONIGHT
ABOUT HIS MOTHER NANCY AND THE
RELATIONSHIP SHE HAD WITH HER
TROUBLED SON.
ACCORDING TO FRIENDS, THE
52-YEAR-OLD DIVORCED MOTHER OF
TWO WAS DEVOTED TO HER CHILDREN
AND WAS ESPECIALLY CLOSE WITH
ADAM WHO FRIENDS SAY WAS VERY
INTELLIGENT BUT SOCIALLY
AWKWARD.
A RETIRED STOCK BROKER FROM NEW
HAMPSHIRE, SHE WAS A LIFELONG
RED SOX FAN WITH SEASON TICKETS
WHO LIVED WITH HER SON ADAM IN A
LARGE COLONIAL HOME NOT FAR FROM
THE CENTER OF HOME.
FRIENDS SAY SHE WAS A
CONTRADICTION.
EXTREMELY GENEROUS AND FRIENDLY,
BUT EXTREMELY PRIVATE WHEN IT
CAME TO HER FAMILY LIFE.
THEY SAID SHE DID TALK ABOUT THE
CHALLENGES OF RAISING A SON WITH
ASPERGER'S SYNDROME, AND DURING
AN INTERVIEW WITH CNN, NANCY'S
FRIENDS SAID SHE MIGHT SOON BE
MOVING THERE.
>> SHE WAS TALKING ABOUT
WASHINGTON STATE, AND SHE WAS
READY TO CHANGE HER WHOLE LIFE,
SELL HER HOUSE AND START OVER
JUST FOR HIM, JUST SO HE COULD
GO TO SCHOOL AND -- I MEAN, HE
WAS -- HE WAS HER LIFE.
>> FRIENDS SAY NANCY LANZA WAS A
GUN ENTHUSIAST AND HAD TAKEN UP
TARGET SHOOTING AS A HOBBY WHEN
SHE INTRODUCED TO HER SON ADAM,
BUT THEY INSIST SHE WAS ALWAYS
RESPONSIBLE WITH GUNS.
>> THEY PAINTED HER AS SOME
IRRESPONSIBLE GUN FREAK, BUT SHE
WASN'T.
SHE WAS -- SHE WAS THE EPITOME
OF RESPONSIBILITY.
SHE WAS A PARAGON FOR GUN
SAFETY.
SHE TAUGHT THE BOYS HOW TO USE
THE GUNS RESPONSIBLY.
>> LITTLE DID SHE KNOW THAT THE
SON SHE DOTED ON AND TAUGHT HOW
TO USE GUNS WOULD TURN THOSE
GUNS ON HER AND CHILDREN.
AUTHORITIES BELIEVE THAT ADAM
LANZA SHOT AND KILLED HER MOTHER
AS SHE WAS LYING IN BED BEFORE
TAKING HER GUNS, TWO OF HER
HANDGUNS AND AN ASSAULT RIFLE,
TO SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
I SAT DOWN WITH SOME OF NANCY'S
FRIENDS AT ONE OF HER FAVORITE
PLACES IN NEWTOWN, A PLACE SHE
WENT TO TWO TO THREE TIMES A
WEEK, AND I ASKED THEM ABOUT WHO
WAS NANCY LANLZA.
>> ABOUT 12 YEARS AGO, 12, 13
YEARS AGO.
YEAH, MET HER IN THE BAR.
SHE COME IN HERE AND HAD
TAKE-OUT FOOD.
WE GOT TO KNOW EACH OTHER.
WITH MARK, YOU KNOW, WE USED TO
TALK IN THE BAR.
YOU KNOW, JUST LIKE CLICKED.
THAT WAS IT.
YOU KNOW, WE STARTED TALKING.
WE BECAME GOOD FRIENDS.
>> GOT TO KNOW HER?
>> YEAH.
YEAH, LIKE I SAID, SHE STARTED
COMING TO THE TAKE-OUT AREA,
PICKING UP FOOD.
SHE GOT TO KNOW OUR FAMILY
PRETTY WELL.
AND SHE WAS VERY FRIENDLY,
OUTGOING.
SHE WAS FUNNY.
WE TOOK TO HER.
YEAH, SHE BECAME FAST FRIENDS
WITH US.
YOU KNOW.
SHE DID A LOT IN TOWN.
WAS ALWAYS ON THE GO.
>> HOW OFTEN DID SHE COME IN
HERE?
SOUNDS LIKE YOU KNOW HER WELL.
WAS THIS KIND OF HER REGULAR
PLACE?
>> YEAH.
TWO TO THREE TIMES A WEEK.
>> TWO TO THREE TIMES A WEEK?
>> FOR FOOD, ESPECIALLY.
THE BAR, NOT SO OFTEN.
YOU KNOW.
>> WHEN SHE HAD TICKETS FOR US
TO THE BALL GAMES.
WE USED TO GO TO THE BOSTON
GAMES.
>> SHE HAD TICKETS TO THE RED
SOX, SO SHE WOULD INVITE US OR
GIVE US THE TICKETS.
>> WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME SHE
CAME IN?
>> I SAW HER LAST WEEK OR TWO
WEEKS AGO TOPS.
SHE CAME IN AND I WAS TALKING TO
HER FOR A LITTLE BIT.
AS FAR AS THIS, SHE CAME TO PICK
UP FOOD MORE THAN ANYTHING ELSE
DURING THE WEEK.
>> YOU DIDN'T MEET THE BOYS,
RIGHT?
>> RIGHT.
>> YOU KNEW ONE OF THEM?
>> BOTH OF THEM.
RYAN WORKED FOR ME FOR A YEAR
AND A HALF WHEN HE WAS IN HIGH
SCHOOL.
HE WAS A BUSKER.
ADAM WAS NEVER A SOCIAL PERSON.
HE USED TO COME IN AND KEEP HIS
HEAD DOWN.
HE WAS NEVER SURE OF HIMSELF.
>> YOU KNEW THERE WAS
SOMETHING --
>> SHE HAD TOLD US THAT, YOU
KNOW, HE HAD A -- A CONDITION
THERE, ASPERGER'S WHERE HE WAS,
YOU KNOW, ALWAYS HAD AN ISSUE IN
SCHOOL SOCIALLY WITH THAT.
HE WAS A HIGHLY INTELLIGENT KID,
VERY HIGH IQ.
GRADUATED AROUND TENTH GRADE OR
SO.
>> SO GRADUATED FROM HIGH SCHOOL
EARLY?
>> YEAH, I THINK SO.
LIKE TENTH GRADE.
YEAH, VERY, VERY INTELLIGENT
KID.
AND I MENTIONED EARLIER, TOO, A
LOT OF PEOPLE ARE MENTIONING
ASPERGER'S.
AND I WOULD LIKE TO SAY
SOMETHING ABOUT THAT.
I THINK THAT A LOT OF KIDS HAVE
IT, AND I DON'T THINK IT HAS
ANYTHING TO DO WITH THE
SITUATION AT ALL BECAUSE KIDS
WITH THAT KNOW THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN RIGHT AND WRONG.
>> SHE TALKED -- NANCY TALKED
OVER THE YEARS ABOUT HER SONS?
>> WHEN SHE CAME IN HERE, WE
SOCIALIZED AND WENT OUT.
WE NEVER TALKED ABOUT THE
FAMILY.
IT WAS HER -- SHE JUST CAME IN
TO HAVE A GREAT TIME, TO TALK.
>> GET IT OFF HER MIND, IF
ANYTHING.
SHE DID, BUT SHE WOULD ONLY SAY
HE WAS -- YOU KNOW, IT'S BEEN
HARD FOR HER, YOU KNOW.
IT WAS REALLY HARD FOR HER,
BRINGING HIM UP.
AND SHE WAS ALWAYS --
>> TALKED ABOUT IT.
>> SHE WAS ALWAYS ON IT.
YEAH, JUST SAYING, YEAH, NEVER
REALLY -- DIDN'T HAVE TO COME IN
AND TALK ABOUT IT.
SHE DIDN'T WANT TO TALK ABOUT
IT.
SHE WOULD MENTION IT'S BEEN
DIFFICULT.
YOU KNOW, I DID SO MUCH FOR HIM
TO TRY TO GET HIM HELP HERE OR
THERE OR DOING DIFFERENT THINGS.
>> ONE OF THE THINGS WE HEARD A
LOT ABOUT HER IS SHE WAS
PASSIONATE ABOUT GUNS.
SHE COLLECTED GUNS.
IS THAT SOMETHING THAT YOU KNEW
ABOUT OR WERE SURPRISED WHEN YOU
HEAR?
>> I WOULD SAY IN THE LAST THREE
YEARS OR SO, SHE PICKED UP THAT
HOBBY.
I DON'T KNOW WHO GOT HER INTO
IT, BUT SHE REALLY ENJOYED IT.
TARGET SHOOTING.
SO I DIDN'T KNOW.
I HAD NO IDEA -- YEAH.
>> NOT COLLECTING GUNS?
>> SHE WAS A TARGET SHOOTER.
SHE PROBABLY HAD SOME GUNS SHE
USED TO TAKE TO THE RANGE AND
PRACTICE WITH.
WHERE DON'T KNOW WHAT SHE OWNED
OR WHAT SHE SAID.
SHE SAID SHE ENJOYED IT, AND
THAT WAS IT.
WE DON'T KNOW IF SHE
SONS, DIDN'T TAKE HER SONS.
SHE DIDN'T TALK ABOUT IT MUCH.
I TOOK IT UP, IT WAS FUN, THAT
KIND OF THING.
>> GIVEN YOU KNEW HER AS A
PERSON, DO YOU THINK SHE WAS A
PERSON WHO WOULD HAVE THE GUNS
AROUND THE HOUSE?
WOULD THEY HAVE BEEN LOCKED UP?
>> THEY WOULD HAVE BEEN LOCKED
UP.
>> FAR TOO BRIGHT FOR THAT.
VERY SMART.
SHE WAS REALLY FUN.
SHE UNDERSTOOD.
>> WHAT DO YOU THINK SOME OF THE
BIGGEST MISCONCEPTIONS ARE THAT
YOU HAVE HEARD ON THE NEWS?
>> I THINK MOSTLY THE, YOU KNOW,
WELL, BETWEEN THE CONDITION THAT
HE HAD, WHICH PEOPLE GET
CONFUSED FOR BEING THE REASON,
AND THE GUNS.
YOU KNOW, WE DON'T THINK THAT
HAS ANYTHING TO DO WITH HER
CHARACTER.
>> SHE DONATED HER TIME FOR ALL
CHARITABLE WORK, HELPING PEOPLE
WHO NEEDED HELP.
HELPING AIDS PEOPLE, DONATING
MONEY FOR AIDS AND CHARITY.
THAT'S WHAT SHE DID.
SHE DIDN'T -- SHE DIDN'T GET
PAID FOR DOING WHAT SHE DID.
SHE DID ALL CHARITABLE WORK ON
HER OWN.
>> VERY GENEROUS?
>> VERY GENEROUS.
VERY GENEROUS.
A PERSON COULD BE SITTING HERE
AND SAY, YOU'RE TALKING TO HER,
AND THEY HAPPEN TO BE SAYING,
YOU KNOW, I DON'T SHAVE MONEY FR
THIS OR HAVE MONEY FOR THAT.
SHE WOULD DIG OUT HER CHECKBOOK
AND WRITE A CHECK AND GIVE IT TO
THE PERSON WITHOUT KNOWING THEM.
THAT'S THE KIND OF PERSON SHE
WAS.
>> ALL RIGHT, I WANT TO BRING IN
SUSAN CANDIOTTI.
SHE HAS THE LATEST ON THE
INVESTIGATION.
I KNOW WE WERE HEARING THE
FRIENDS OF NANCY LANZA TALKING
ABOUT HOW SHE PICKED UP THE GUN
HOBBY OVER THE PAST THREE YEARS.
THEY WERE VERY ADAMANT SHE
WOULDN'T HAVE BEEN THE KIND OF
PERSON TO HAVE LET HER GUNS
LOOSE.
SHE WOULD HAVE LOCKED THEM UP.
WHAT ARE YOU LEARNING ABOUT
TARGET SHOOTING, NANCY LANZA,
AND ADAM?
>> THAT'S ONE OF THE THINGS
INVESTIGATORS HAVE TO LOOK AT.
WHAT WERE BOTH OF THEM DOING IN
THE MONTHS LEADING UP TO THIS?
IN PARTICULAR, HER SON, THE
SUSPECTED SHOOTER IN THE CASE?
THEY'RE FINDING OUT MORE ABOUT
THAT.
THEY'RE LEARNING IN FACT BOTH
MOTHER AND SON HAD BEEN TO
TARGET PRACTICE, DID GO TO GUN
RANGES SEVERAL TIMES OVER THE
PAST SEVERAL YEARS.
THEY DON'T KNOW EXACTLY HOW
OFTEN YET, BUT MOST RECENTLY FOR
ADAM, ANYWAY, IN THE LAST SIX
YEARS AND OVER THE COURSE OF
SEVERAL YEARS.
THE REASON THEY DON'T KNOW THE
BIG PICTURE, THE FULL PICTURE IS
ATF IS STILL CANVASSING ALL OF
THE GUN RANGES IN THE AREA, AND
THERE ARE A TON OF THEM, TO GET
MORE INFORMATION ABOUT THIS.
THEY'RE STILL FOLLOWING A LOT OF
LEADS, AND THEY'RE ALSO LOOKING
AT COMPUTERS, COMPUTER SAID THEY
HAVE DISCOVERED IN THE HOME.
A COUPLE OF THEM, WE LEARNED
FROM OUR LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS, IS THAT THEY WERE
SMASHED.
SMASHED TO SMITH ARENES.
>> HE TRIED TO DESTROY THE
EVIDENCE?
>> THAT APPEARS TO BE THE CASE,
THE APPARENT INDICATION.
THEY HAVE HAD TO PICK UP THE
PIECES, LITERALLY, PULL THINGS
TOGETHER, TRY TO EXAMINE THE
HARD DRIVE.
WHAT WOULD THEY BE LOOKING FOR?
OBVIOUSLY, CHECKING TO SEE IF HE
SENT E-MAILS TO ANYONE, WHAT
WEBSITES DID HE VISIT?
WAS HE IN CHAT ROOMS, MESSAGE
BOARDS?
GIVE ANY INDICATION TO A
POSSIBLE MOTIVE IN ALL THIS?
WHO DID HE COMMUNICATE WITH, IF
ANYONE?
THOSE ARE THE KINDS OF THINGS
THEY'RE LOOKING AT.
AND REMEMBER, THEY ARE ALSO
DOING A COMPLETE HISTORY OF ALL
OF THE WEAPONS THAT WERE USED IN
THIS TERRIBLE TRAGEDY.
WE'VE GOT THE ONE MADE BY
BUSHMASTER, WHICH WAS THAT
ASSAULT-TYPE RIFLE, AND WE KNOW
HE CAME, ACCORDING TO OFFICIALS,
WITH A TON OF AMMUNITION.
HE WAS ARMED TO THE HILT WHEN HE
WENT TO THAT SCHOOL.
MULTIPLE MAGAZINES FOR ALL THREE
WEAPONS.
>> HUNDREDS OF BULLETS THAT WERE
NOT USED.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
EXTRA BULLETS ON TOP OF THAT.
30-ROUND MAGAZINES.
A LOT TO GO OVER.
THEY'RE GOING TO BE LOOKING AT
ALL OF THAT.
WE WERE ALSO THERE YESTERDAY
WHEN WE SAW HIS CAR BEING TOWED
AWAY.
THEY'RE GOING TO BE GOING OVER
THAT VEHICLE FROM TOP TO BOTTOM,
INSIDE THE TRUNK, YOU'LL
REMEMBER, WAS AN EXTRA RIFLE.
>> I KNOW WE DON'T YET KNOW
ABOUT MOTIVE, AND WHEN THEY GET
THIS INFORMATION, THEY'LL TRY TO
GET MORE AND MORE INFORMATION,
BUT WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT HIM
PLAYING VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES?
>> WE DON'T KNOW MUCH ABOUT THAT
YET.
THAT'S ONE THING, OF COURSE,
THEY'LL BE LOOKING FOR.
WHAT INDICATION OF GAMES DO
DOWNLOADED TO THE COMPUTER.
TODAY I SPOKE WITH A FRIENDS OF
HIS -- I GUESS YOU WOULD CALL A
FRIEND OF HIS, WHO WENT TO HIGH
SCHOOL WITH HIM.
HE SAID IN THEIR TECH CLASSES,
THEY WOULD PLAY A COUPLE GAMES
CALLED STAR CRAFT AND WAR CRAFT,
WHICH INVOLVED SHOOTING UP
ENEMIES AND THIS KIND OF THING.
>> KILLING AND AWFUL THINGS.
THANK YOU, SUSAN.
WE APPRECIATE IT.
SUSAN WITH THE LATEST ON THE
INVESTIGATION AND WHAT WE KNOW
AND AT THIS POINT WHAT WE DON'T
KNOW.
>> "OUTFRONT" NEXT, THE WOMAN
WHO WROTE THE BLOG, I AM ADAM
LANZA'S MOTHER, CALLING
ATTENTION TO RAISING A CHILD
WITH A SERIOUS MENTAL ILLNESS.
WHAT SHE GOT WAS A FIRESTORM.
SHE RESPONDS TO THE CONTROVERSY
AND CRITICISM NEXT.
>> LATER, THE PRINCIPAL HERO
REMEMBERED BY THE PEOPLE WHO
KNEW HER.
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU ARE A BUSINESS PRO.
OMNIPOTENT OF OPPORTUNITY.
YOU KNOW HOW TO MIX BUSINESS...
WITH BUSINESS.
AND YOU...RENT FROM NATIONAL.
BECAUSE ONLY NATIONAL LETS YOU
CHOOSE ANY CAR IN THE AISLE.
AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE A FULL-SIZE
OR ABOVE.
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
I COULD GET USED TO THIS.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, YOU COULD BUSINESS PRO.
YES, YOU COULD.
GO NATIONAL. GO LIKE A PRO.
A REGULAR GUY
WITH AN IRREGULAR HEARTBEAT.
THE USUAL, BOB?
NOT TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
BOB HAS AFIB:
ATRIAL FIBRILLATION NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
A CONDITION THAT PUTS HIM
AT GREATER RISK FOR A STROKE.
[ GPS ] TURN LEFT.
I DON'T THINK SO.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR YEARS, BOB TOOK WARFARIN,
AND MADE A MONTHLY TRIP TO THE
CLINIC TO GET HIS BLOOD TESTED.
BUT NOT ANYMORE.
BOB'S DOCTOR RECOMMENDED
A DIFFERENT OPTION:
ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
XARELTO® IS THE FIRST AND ONLY
ONCE-A-DAY PRESCRIPTION
BLOOD THINNER
FOR PATIENTS WITH AFIB
NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
THAT DOESN'T REQUIRE
ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING.
LIKE WARFARIN,
XARELTO® IS PROVEN EFFECTIVE
TO REDUCE THE RISK
OF AN AFIB-RELATED STROKE.
THERE IS LIMITED DATA
ON HOW THESE DRUGS COMPARE
WHEN WARFARIN IS WELL MANAGED.
NO ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING
MEANS BOB CAN SPEND HIS
EXTRA TIME HOWEVER HE LIKES.
NEW ZEALAND!
XARELTO®
IS JUST ONE PILL A DAY,
TAKEN WITH THE EVENING MEAL.
AND WITH
NO DIETARY RESTRICTIONS,
BOB CAN EAT THE HEALTHY FOODS
HE LIKES.
DO NOT STOP TAKING
XARELTO® RIVAROXABAN
WITHOUT TALKING TO THE DOCTOR
WHO PRESCRIBES IT FOR YOU.
STOPPING MAY INCREASE YOUR RISK
OF HAVING A STROKE.
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU DEVELOP ANY SIGNS
OR SYMPTOMS OF BLEEDING,
LIKE UNUSUAL BRUISING
OR TINGLING.
YOU MAY HAVE A HIGHER RISK
OF BLEEDING
IF YOU TAKE XARELTO®
WITH ASPIRIN PRODUCTS,
NSAIDS OR BLOOD THINNERS.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE TAKING XARELTO®
IF YOU CURRENTLY HAVE
ABNORMAL BLEEDING.
XARELTO® CAN CAUSE BLEEDING,
WHICH CAN BE SERIOUS,
AND RARELY MAY LEAD TO DEATH.
YOU ARE LIKELY TO BRUISE
MORE EASILY ON XARELTO®,
AND IT MAY TAKE LONGER
FOR BLEEDING TO STOP.
TELL YOUR DOCTORS
YOU ARE TAKING XARELTO®
BEFORE ANY PLANNED MEDICAL
OR DENTAL PROCEDURES.
BEFORE STARTING XARELTO®,
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ANY CONDITIONS,
SUCH AS KIDNEY, LIVER
OR BLEEDING PROBLEMS.
READY TO CHANGE YOUR ROUTINE?
ASK YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
FOR MORE INFORMATION
INCLUDING COST SUPPORT OPTIONS,
CALL 1-888-XARELTO
OR VISIT GOXARELTO.COM.
>>> I AM ADAM LANZA'S MOTHER.
THAT TITLE FOR A BLOG POSTING
FOR A MOTHER IN IDAHO WENT VIRAL
ABOUT THE INSTANT AFTER IT WAS
PUBLISHED.
LIZA LONG WROTE VIVIDLY ABOUT
HER 13-YEAR-OLD SON MICHAEL.
SHE CHANGED HIS NAME, SHE SAYS,
TO PROTECT HIS PRIVACY.
HERE'S WHAT SHE WROTE.
I LIVE WITH A SON WHO IS
MENTALLY ILL.
I LOVE MY SON, BUT HE TERRIFIES
ME.
A FEW WEEKS AGO, MICHAEL PULLED
A KNIFE AND THREATENED TO KILL
ME AND THEN HIMSELF AFTER I
ASKED HIM TO RETURN HIS OVERDUE
LIBRARY BOOKS.
NOW THIS BLOG WAS -- IT WAS VERY
RAW AND EMOTIONAL AND IT RAISED
QUESTIONS ABOUT PARENTING A
CHILD WITH MENTAL ILLNESS, AND
THERE WERE A LOT OF CRITICS.
PEOPLE WONDERING WHY LIZA LONG
WOULD CHOOSE TO BE SO PUBLIC
ABOUT HER SON MICHAEL.
I SPOKE TO HER AND ASKED HER WHY
SHE WROTE THE BLOG.
>> THIS BLOG WAS A REALLY
PERSONAL AND VISCERAL RESPONSE
TO THIS ABSOLUTELY TRAGIC
SHOOTING THAT OCCURRED IN
CONNECTICUT ON FRIDAY.
AND WHEN I HEARD ABOUT THE
SHOOTINGS, I CLOSED MY OFFICE
DOOR AND JUST STARTED TO SHAKE.
AND LATER THAT EVENING AS I SAT
DOWN, I CONFRONTED A LOT OF MY
OWN FEARS AND THOUGHT PROCESS
THAT I HAD BEEN GOING THROUGH
JUST DURING THE COURSE OF THAT
WEEK.
AND THAT BLOG POST WAS A RESULT
OF THAT REALLY HARD LOOK AT MY
OWN LIFE AND MY OWN
CIRCUMSTANCES.
>> AND LIZA, YOU WRITE ABOUT --
I MEAN, I'M GOING TO USE YOUR
WORDS.
I KNOW THIS IS HARD TO SAY.
YOU WRITE ABOUT YOUR CHILD
THREATENING YOU WITH A KNIFE,
WHICH IS NORMAL BEHAVIOR FOR
HIM?
>> THAT'S THE SCARY THING, ERIN.
THE EXTENT TO WHICH WE HAD
NORMAL LIFE, THAT BEHAVIOR, WHAT
I TRY TO DESCRIBE MICHAEL TO
PEOPLE, ANYONE WHO KNOWS HIM
KNOWS THAT 97% OF THE TIME, HE'S
JUST THE SWEETEST, BRIGHTEST,
KINDEST, MOST ARTICULATE CHILD.
BUT SOMETIMES FOR NO APPARENT
REASON, HE WILL TURN INTO THIS
ABSOLUTE RAGING -- I DON'T KNOW
HOW TO DESCRIBE IT.
YOU WOULD HAVE TO SEE IT TO
BELIEVE IT.
I STOPPED AND SAID TO MYSELF,
THIS ISN'T NORMAL.
I HAVE TO FACE UP TO THE FACT
THAT I HAVE A SICK SON, AND WE
NEED HELP.
AND ERIN, THAT'S REALLY WHAT THE
BLOG POST WAS ABOUT.
IT WAS ABOUT -- IT WAS A CRY FOR
HELP.
IN A SITUATION WHERE I WAS
FEELING VERY HELPLESS.
>> AND DO YOU KNOW WHAT HE HAS?
WHAT CAUSES HIM TO DO THIS?
HAS IT EVER BEEN DIAGNOSED?
>> WE HAVE HAD A VARIETY OF
DIAGNOSES.
WE HAVE LOOKED AT OPPOSITIONAL
SOCIETAL DISORDER, INTERMITTENT
DISORDERS.
HE'S BEEN LOOKED AT FOR AUTISM
SPECTRISM DISORDER AND FINALLY
ALSO ADHD.
>> SO YOU'RE NOT EVEN SURE.
I KNOW TO GIVE THE VIEWERS SOME
BACKGROUND HERE, YOU AND YOUR
HUSBAND, HE HAS ACTUALLY BEEN
INTO JUVENILE DETENTION FOUR
TIMES AND HE'S NOW AT WHAT YOU
CALL AN ACUTE IN-PATIENT
FACILITY, A MENTAL HEALTH
FACILITY, AND YOU TOOK HIM THERE
AFTER THE NIGHT OF THE INCIDENT.
WHEN YOU WRITE ABOUT THE MOMENT,
I'LL READ IT, MICHAEL WAS IN A
FULL-BLOWN FIT, SCREAMING AND
HITTING.
I HUGGED HIM CLOSE SO HE
COULDN'T ESCAPE FROM THE CAR.
HE BIT ME SEVERAL TIMES AND
REPEATEDLY JABBED HIS ELBOWS IN
MY RIB CAGE.
I'M STILL STRONGER THAN HE IS,
BUT I WON'T BE FOR MUCH LONGER.
HOW LONG WILL HE BE IN THE
MENTAL HEALTH INSTITUTION AND
WHAT WILL YOU DO WHEN HE COMES
HOME?
>> ERIN, THAT'S THE REASON I
WROTE THE BLOG.
PEOPLE HAVE HAD A HARD TIME
UNDERSTANDING THIS, BUT WHERE WE
LIVE, I DON'T KNOW HOW IT IS
WHERE YOU LIVE, BUT WHERE WE
LIVE, MENTAL HEALTH TREATMENT IS
PRETTY SHORT-TERM, SO THIS
FACILITY FOR YOUNG ADULTS, 10 TO
14 DAYS MAYBE AT THE MOST.
MAYBE EVEN LESS.
AND AFTER THAT, THERE JUST
REALLY AREN'T A LOT OF OPTIONS
FOR CONTINUED RESIDENTIAL
TREATMENT HERE.
THAT'S THE BIGGEST CHALLENGE I'M
FACING, THE ADVICE I GOT WAS
THAT I NEEDED TO PRESS CHARGES
SO THAT WE COULD CREATE A PAPER
TRAIL AGAIN.
AND HE DID GET EXCELLENT
FOLLOW-THROUGH CARE WHEN HE HAD
TO DO JUVENILE DETENTION AS A
YOUNGER BOY.
BUT I JUST DON'T FEEL LIKE JAIL
IS THE RIGHT PLACE FOR MY SON.
AND I'M JUST REALLY HOPING THAT
WE CAN FIND ANOTHER SOLUTION FOR
HIM.
>> YOU HAVE BEEN CRITICIZED, OF
COURSE, FOR WRITING THIS BLOG.
I KNOW YOU'RE WELL AWARE OF
THAT.
YOU WROTE IT UNDER YOUR OWN NAME
SO PEOPLE COULD FIGURE OUT WHO
YOUR SON IS.
MICHAEL ISN'T HIS REAL NAME, BUT
ANYONE WHO KNEW YOU COULD FIGURE
IT OUT.
YOU HAVE BEEN CRITICIZED FOR
DOING THAT, MAYBE IF HE DOES
GROW UP AND IS ABLE TO BECOME A
FUNCTIONING MEMBER OF SOCIETY,
THIS WOULD DOG HIM FOR THE REST
OF HIS LIFE.
YOUR WORDS WOULD BE THERE.
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THAT?
>> THOSE KINDS OF CRITICISMS ARE
GOING TO COME UP ANY TIME
THERE'S A SITUATION LIKE THIS.
FIRST AND FOREMOST, AND I
REALIZE THIS SOUNDS HOPELESSLY
NAIVE, I DID BELIEVE MY BLOG WAS
ANONYMO
ANONYMOUS.
IF YOU LOOK AT IT, MY NAME
WASN'T IN THERE.
MY LINK WAS IN THE BLUE REVIEW
AND THAT WAS LINKED TO MY BLOG.
YOU KNOW, HONESTLY, AS YOU
PROBABLY KNOW, THERE'S A GREAT
WOMAN NAMED SARAH OUT THERE WHO
HAS A WONDERFUL BLOG, SHAEZ E'SY
ARTICULATE AND PASSIONATE AND
CONCERNED ABOUT CHILDREN'S
PRIVACY ISSUES.
I THINK HER CONCERNS ARE
LEGITIMATE.
HER CONCERNS ABOUT CHILDREN'S
PRIVACY ISSUES ARE LEGITIMATE.
HIGH SON DOES KNOW ABOUT THE
PIECE.
HIS TAKE ON IT WAS, MOM, IF WE
CAN HELP PEOPLE UNDERSTAND, THIS
IS A GOOD THING.
>> LIZA, LET ME ASK YOU BECAUSE
YOU MENTIONED SARAH.
AND THAT'S WHO YOU'RE REFERRING
TO.
SHE'S ANOTHER MOM WHO WAS
INCREDIBLY CRITICAL OF YOU.
YOU HAVE TALKED AND YOU PUT OUT
A JOINT STATEMENT SAYING LOOK,
AMERICA, LET'S HAVE A
CONVERSATION ABOUT MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES.
WHEN SHE POSTED ONLINE, YOU
WROTE THINGS ABOUT YOUR SON'S
BEHAVIOR.
I'LL QUOTE YOU AGAIN, IT MAKES
ME WANT TO THROTTLE YOU, I QUIT,
LET THE STATE TAKE CARE OF YOU.
YOU WROTE, MY DAYDREAMS ALL
INVOLVED MY OWN DEATH?
ARE THOSE EMOTIONS YOU FEEL AS A
MOTHER AND PEOPLE DON'T SAY,
WERE YOU EXAGGERATING?
TELL ME HOW THAT HAPPENED?
>> FIRST OF ALL, I HAVE TO ADMIT
THAT YOU GUYS HAVE SCRUTINIZED
MY BLOG A WHOLE LOT MORE THAN I
THOUGHT IT WOULD BE SCRUTINIZED.
I DON'T THINK ANYONE IN AMERICA
THINKS ANYONE READS THEIR BLOGS.
YEAH, I THINK ONE OF THE HA
HALLMARKS OF MY WRITING AND ONE
OF THE REASONS THE LAST PIECE
CONNECTED WITH SO MANY PEOPLE IS
THAT I DO HAVE A TENDENCY TO
KIND OF SAY WHAT'S ON MY MIND.
YOU KNOW, I WROTE THOSE WORDS,
AND THOSE ARE MY WORDS.
I'M NOT DISOWNING THEM, BUT
YOU'RE LOOKING AT A FOUR-YEAR --
THAT'S A FOUR-YEAR SLICE OF
HISTORY.
>> LET ME ASK YOU A QUESTION.
DO YOU OWN A GUN?
>> HEAVENS NO.
NO, NO, NO.
NO.
>> OKAY.
BECAUSE OBVIOUSLY, YOU'RE
WRITING ABOUT MENTAL HEALTH.
SOME PEOPLE HAVE SAID, LOOK, YOU
HAVE FAIR POINTS, LIZA, BUT
DON'T LET THIS OBSCURE THE
NATIONAL DEBATE WE NEED TO HAVE
ABOUT GUN CONTROL AND WHAT WE
NEED TO DO.
>> OH, MY GOODNESS, NO.
I HEARD THAT FROM MORE THAN ONE
PERSON.
I THINK THE QUESTION IS IT'S
SOMETHING ABOUT IT'S EASY TO
TALK ABOUT GUN CONTROL BUT IT'S
TIME TO TALK ABOUT MENTAL
HEALTH.
IF I CAN CLARIFY, WHAT I MEAN IS
EASY IS WE CAN FRAME THE GUN
CONTROL DEBATE IN TERMS OF RIGHT
AND WRONG.
YOU KNOW, IT'S RIGHT TO HAVE GUN
CONTROL.
OR IT'S WRONG, AS SOME PEOPLE
WOULD SAY, TO HAVE GUN CONTROL.
THAT'S A SIMPLE WAY TO DEBATE A
QUESTION.
I DON'T THINK YOU CAN SAY THAT
MENTAL HEALTH IS RIGHT OR WRONG.
>> YEAH, ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH, LIZA.
I APPRECIATE YOU TAKING THE TIME
AND COMING AND TALKING ABOUT
THIS.
>> THANK YOU, ERIN.
I REALLY APPRECIATE YOU
HIGHLIGHTING THIS IMPORTANT
ISSUE OF MENTAL HEALTH.
I REALLY FEEL LIKE THIS IS A
CONVERSATION WE NEED TO HAVE AS
A NATION.
WE NEED TO DO SOMETHING FOR OUR
CHILDREN AND ADULTS WHO STRUGGLE
WITH BEHAVIORAL AND MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES.
>> WE CERTAINLY DO.
THANKS.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> NOW, I ASKED LIZA WHY SHE
HAD PUT A PICTURE UP OF HER SON
ON HER BLOG SINCE SHE CHANGED
HIS NAME AND WANTED TO PROTECT
HIS PRIVACY.
SHE WAS OPEN.
SHE SAID THE PICTURE OF HIM WAS
AT AGE 7.
HE LOOKS NOTHING LIKE THAT NOW.
HE'S 13 YEARS OLD.
I WANT TO BRING IN DR. SANJAY
GUPTA.
HOST OF SANJAY GUPTA M.D.
WHEN YOU HEAR LIZA TALK ABOUT
HER CHILD AND HIS STRUGGLES,
SHE'S TAKEN A LOT OF CRITICISM.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
>> IT WAS A GOOD INTERVIEW.
YOU GOT THE SENSE IT WAS A
LITTLE THERAPEUTIC FOR HER, HER
WRITING.
SHE WRITES THIS STUFF.
SEEING HER, MIEETING HER THROUG
THE INTERVIEW, YOU CAN TELL
SHE'S NOT THE KIND OF MOM WHO IS
GOING TO DO THOSE THINGS.
SHE'S FRUSTRATED.
IMAGINE THE THRESHOLD TO GET
YOUR CHILD TREATMENT IS THEY
HAVE TO BE IMMINENT HARM TO
THEMSELVES OR OTHER PEOPLE.
THAT'S LIKE SAYING YOU CAN ONLY
GO TO THE HOSPITAL IF YOU'RE
ALREADY HAVING A HEART ATTACK.
THAT DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
THAT'S THE PROBLEM WHEN YOU TALK
ABOUT PUTTING MENTAL HEALTH ON
PAR WITH PHYSICAL HEALTH.
IT'S NOT RIGHT NOW.
>> IT WAS HARD WHEN YOU HAVE TO
GUARD YOUR CHIARGE YOUR CHILD
WITH BATTERY OR ASSAULT TO GET
THEM CARE.
YOU HAVE DONE THE NUMBERS, 1 IN
5 CHILDREN HAVE A MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUE IN THIS COUNTRY.
THAT'S AN AMAZING NUMBER.
>> THAT IS AN AMAZING NUMBER,
AND THE MENTAL HEALTH RESOURCES
AREN'T THERE.
WHEN YOU PRESCRIBE A MEDICATION
OR TAKE SOMEONE OFF A
MEDICATION, ALL THE LITERATURE
SAYS YOU HAVE TO MONITOR A
PERSON.
YOU KNOW AS WELL AS I DO, THEY
GET PRESCRIPTIONS AND THEY DON'T
GET THE FOLLOW-UP.
THAT'S A REAL PROBLEM.
IT'S SOMETHING THAT COMES UP IN
A TRAGEDY HERE.
>> IT SEEMS THAT A LOT OF
PARENTS WOULD BE UNDERSTANDABLY
IN DENIAL.
MY CHILD DOESN'T HAVE A PROBLEM,
OR THEY'RE GOING TO GROW OUT OF
IT.
NOBODY WANTS TO BE THAT -- BE IN
THAT POSITION.
>> I THINK DENIAL IS A BIG PART
OF THIS.
YOU KNOW, ERIN, I HAVE BEEN
TALKING TO A LOT OF PEOPLE.
WHAT I'M HEARING MORE THAN
ANYTHING ELSE IS ANGUISH OVER
WHAT IS HAPPENING WITH THEIR
CHILDREN.
THEY WOULD LOVE TO GET TREATMENT
FOR THEIR CHILDREN, BUT IT MEANS
GIVING THEM A CRIMINAL RECORD OR
SAYING THEY ARE GOING TO HURT
PEOPLE.
THAT'S A TOUGH CHOICE TO MAKE.
>> YOU CAN SEE THE ANGUISH.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>>> UP NEXT, WE'LL BRING YOU
SOME OF OUR OTHER TOP STORIES
FROM THE DAY.
WE HAVE MORE FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, INCLUDING THE STORY
OF A MAN WHO FOUND CHILDREN ON
HIS FRONT LAWN, VICTIMS OF A
HORRIBLE CRIME THE WORLD AT THAT
MOMENT KNEW NOTHING ABOUT.
YOU CAN STAY IN
AND LIKE SOMETHING...
OR YOU CAN GET OUT THERE
AND ACTUALLY LIKE SOMETHING.
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
>>> WELCOME BACK.
TONIGHT, WE START THE SECOND
HALF OF OUR SHOW WITH OTHER KEY
STORIES WE'RE WATCHING TONIGHT.
WE BEGUN WITH DEMOCRAT DANIEL
ANEWY, THE SENATE'S MOST SENIOR
OLDER MEMBER DIED TODAY.
HE REPRESENTED HAWAII AND WAS
THE SECOND LONGEST SERVING
MEMBER IN THE HISTORY.
A WORLD WAR II VETERAN.
HE WAS HOSPITALIZED LAST WEEK
BUT EVENTUALLY SUCCUMBED TO
RESPIRATORY COMPLICATIONS.
WE'RE TOLD HIS LAST WORD WAS
ALOHA.
>> FISCAL CLIFF TALKS MAY BE
GAINING SOME MOMENTUM.
PRESIDENT OBAMA MET WITH HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER AFTER
BOEHNER INDICATED HE WAS WILLING
TO MAKE NEW CONCESSIONS.
IT WAS A FACE-TO-FACE MEETING,
THEIR THIRD IN EIGHT DAYS.
A DPEEAL COULD HELP THE COUNTRY
GET OUR AAA RATING BACK.
ELSEWHERE IN POLITICS, A BIG
DECISION IN SOUTH CAROLINA.
GOVERNOR NIKKI HALEY HAS
REPRESENTED KIM SCOTT TO REPLACE
OUTGOING SENATOR JIM DeMINT.
SCOTT WILL BE THE SENATE'S ONLY
BLACK MEMBER, BUT WILL ONLY HOLD
THE POSITION UNTIL THE ELECTION
IN 2014.
YOU MAIL RECALL THAT EARLIER
THIS MONTH, DeMINT SAID HE WAS
RESIGNING FROM THE SENATE BY
JANUARY 1st TO LEAD A
CONSERVATIVE THINK TANK WHERE HE
SAID HE COULD MAKE A BIGGER
DIFFERENCE THAN HE DOES IN THE
SENATE.
>> AND AN INDEPENDENT REVIEW OF
HOW THE AMERICAN EMBASSY HANDLED
THE ATTACK ON THE CONSULATE.
THEY WILL HAVE A CLOSED-DOOR
BRIEFING ON WEDNESDAY.
THEY'LL BE BRIEFED BY THE
MEMBERS WHO CONDUCTED THE
REVIEW.
>>> WELL, EARLIER TODAY, NEWTOWN
BEGAN THE UNBEARABLE TASK OF
SAYING GOOD-BYE TO TWO OF
FRIDAY'S YOUNGEST VICTIMS.
AS WE WERE COMING INTO NEWTOWN
FROM A DISTANCE, WE SAW A
GRAVEYARD AND A FUNERAL.
AND YOU CHOKE UP AND TEAR UP
JUST SEEING THAT.
IT BRINGS HOME JUST THE
MAGNITUDE OF WHAT HAS HAPPENED
HERE.
6-YEAR-OLDS JACK PINTO AND NOAH
POZNER WERE BOTH LAID TO REST.
NOAH WAS A SMART LITTLE BOY.
HE LOVED READING AND PLAYING
WITH HIS SIBLINGS CALLING HIS
TWIN CENTRAL ASISTER, ARIEL, HI
FRIEND.
JACK PINTO WAS A HUGE FOOTBALL
FAN WHO LOVED THE NEW YORK
GIANTS.
THEY HAVE BEEN COVERING JACK'S
FUNERAL, AND SHE JOINS ME NOW.
I KNOW HE LOVED THE GIANTS.
THAT WAS A REAL AREA OF PASSION
FOR THAT LITTLE BOY.
IT MUST HAVE BEEN HEARTBREAKING
TO BE THERE TODAY.
>> CERTAINLY, BECAUSE IT JUST
DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
WE HAVE BEEN WATCHING WHAT HAS
BEEN HAPPENING TO THIS TOWN, BUT
THEN TO SEE ALL OF THESE PEOPLE
SHOW UP AT THIS LITTLE BOY'S
FUNERAL, JUST A 6-YEAR-OLD BOY
IN THE FIRST GRADE.
THE PEOPLE YOU NORMALLY SEE SHOW
UP AT A FUNERAL, THEY'RE OLDER.
THE PEOPLE WHO CAME TODAY,
CHILDREN, 5-YEAR-OLDS,
6-YEAR-OLDS, 7-YEAR-OLD
CHILDREN.
THEY ARRIVED WEARING LONG
SLEEVED SHIRTS, SWEATSHIRTS THAT
HAD NEWTOWN WRESTLING ON IT.
THE FAMILY HAD ASKED FOR
PRIVACY, SO WE TRIED TO GIVE
THEM AS MUCH PRIVACY AS
POSSIBLE.
YOU THINK ABOUT THE GLOBAL
SPOTLIGHT.
THEY TRIED TO HAVE AS MUCH ALONE
TIME AS POSSIBLE, BUT CERTAINLY
THERE IS A LOT OF INTEREST IN
THIS LITTLE BOY WHO LOVED SPORTS
SO MUCH.
ONE CHILD WHO SHOWED UP TO MOURN
TODAY, HE WAS ACTUALLY WEARING A
MEDAL.
AND THE MEDAL IS SIGNIFICANT
BECAUSE I SPOKE TO A MEMBER OF A
WRESTLING TEAM IN A NEARBY TOWN,
AND THIS TEAM SAYS THAT JACK HAD
JUST WON HIS FIRST MEDAL THIS
LAST WEEK.
HIS VERY FIRST MATCH, HE HAD WON
HIS FIRST MEDAL.
BUT AS YOU MENTIONED, HIS REAL
LOVE WAS FOOTBALL.
HE LOVED THE NEW YORK GIANTS.
HE LOVED VICTOR CRUZ.
AND THAT MESSAGE WENT ALL THE
WAY TO CRUZ.
HE TWEETED OUT THIS PICTURE.
HE TOOK A PICTURE OF HIS CLEATS
AND HIS GLOVES.
THEY HAD THE NAME JACK PINTO ON
IT.
HE SAID, THIS GAME IS FOR YOU.
AND AFTER LAST NIGHT'S GAME,
HERE'S WHAT CRUZ TOLD REPORTERS.
>> IT WAS EMOTIONAL, MAN.
YOU KNOW, I WAS HOLDING BACK
TEARS TO DO IT.
IT FELT GOOD.
IT FELT GOOD TO HONOR A FAMILY
GOING THROUGH SO MUCH.
JUST THE THOUGHT OF YOUR LITTLE
ONE OR YOUR CHILD, YOUR SON OR
DAUGHTER GOING THROUGH SOMETHING
LIKE THAT, IT WAS -- YOU KNOW,
IT WAS UNBELIEVABLE TO EVEN
LISTEN TO ON THE NEWS.
SO I PUT MY DAUGHTER INTO BED
WITH ME THAT NIGHT.
>> THE FAMILY REPORTEDLY WAS SO
MOVED AND KNEW HOW MUCH THEIR
LITTLE BOY LOVED CRUZ THAT THEY
BURIED HIM IN A VICTOR CRUZ
JERSEY.
THIS, ERIN, JUST THE VERY FIRST
OF WHAT WILL BE MANY MORE DAYS
OF FUNERALS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> "OUTFRONT" NEXT, MORE HEROES
FROM THAT DAY.
ONE MAN SAW SIX SMALL CHILDREN
ON HIS FRONT LAWN.
REFUGEES OF HORROR.
HE DIDN'T KNOW WHY.
>> AND VICKY SOTO, A WOMAN WHO
GAVE EVERYTHING FOR HER
CHILDREN, INCLUDING HER LIFE.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
ROBITUSSIN® LIQUID FORMULA
SOOTHES YOUR THROAT ON CONTACT
INCLUDING HER LIFE.
ROBITUSSIN®. DON'T SUFFER
THE COUGHEQUENCES™.
♪
First rule of taking the
world by surprise?
Do something the world
will actually notice.
Introducing the entirely
new Ford Fusion.
With a turbo-charged EcoBoost
engines and a hybrid that
doubles the fuel economy of
the average vehicle.
It's an entirely new idea of
what a car can be.
>>> WE'RE BACK IN NEWTOWN WITH
ANOTHER STORY OF LOVE AND
HEROISM.
LITERALLY DOWN THE ROAD FROM
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, SO
CLOSE THAT FRIDAY MORNING,
BEFORE ANYONE KNEW THE HORROR
THAT HAD HAPPENED, HE DISCOVERED
SIX TERRIFIED CHILDREN ON HIS
FRONT LAWN.
THEY TOLD THEM THEIR TEACHER HAD
JUST BEEN KILLED, AND GENE IS
OUT FRONT WITH ME TONIGHT.
GENE, THANK YOU.
I KNOW IT'S HARD, AND WITH ALL
OF THE MEDIA HERE TO COME AND
TALK ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED.
BUT WHEN YOU SAW THE CHILDREN ON
YOUR YARD, DID YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
THAT SOMETHING WAS WRONG?
>> I HAD NO IDEA.
I THOUGHT THEY WERE DOING A SKIT
OR MAYBE THEY WERE CUB SCOUTS OR
GIRL SCOUTS AND THEY WERE JUST
PRACTICING BECAUSE THEY WERE
SITTING SO NICELY.
BUT THEN I SAW A MAN IN A VERY
AGITATED WAY SAYING IT'S GOING
TO BE ALL RIGHT.
AND HE KEPT RAISING HIS VOICE.
AND I CAME TO THE CHILDREN AND
THEY WERE CRYING AND WAILING AND
MORTIFIED.
AND THERE WAS A SCHOOL BUS
DRIVER WITH THEM, AND I INVITED
THEM INTO THE HOUSE.
AND SHE SAID THERE HAD BEEN AN
INCIDENT AT THE SCHOOL.
I HAD NO IDEA WHAT IT WAS.
>> AND THE CHILDREN, HOW DID
THEY FIND THE WORDS TO TELL YOU?
THEY TOLD YOU, RIGHT?
>> THEY TOLD ME.
THEY JUST STARTED TALKING.
THE TWO BOYS MOSTLY TALKED.
AND THEY SAID, WE CAN'T GO BACK
TO THAT SCHOOL.
WE CAN'T --
>> WE CAN'T GO BACK.
>> OUR TEACHER -- OUR TEACHER IS
DEAD.
WHAT ARE WE GOING TO DO?
WE DON'T HAVE A TEACHER.
AND I WAS -- I COULD NOT TAKE
THAT IN.
I COULD NOT -- I COULD NOT
ACCEPT THAT.
AND I JUST KEPT LISTENING TO
THEM, AND THEN THEY TALKED MORE.
AND THE BOY SAID, OH, NO, IT WAS
A BIG GUN AND A SMALL GUN.
THEN I KNEW.
THEN THEY SAID THERE WAS BLOOD.
THERE WAS BLOOD.
AND THEN THEY SAID HER NAME.
AND I PRAYED THAT IT WASN'T THAT
TEACHER, AND IT WAS.
>> VICKY SOTO.
>> THAT VERY PRETTY 27-YEAR-OLD
TEACHER.
I DON'T KNOW HOW THEY FLED.
I THINK SHE MUST HAVE PROTECTED
THEM AND SAVED THEIR LIVES.
I DON'T KNOW IF THEY RAN ALL THE
WAY DOWN THE BOULEVARD, THE
STREET NEXT TO THE FIRE HOUSE.
I DON'T KNOW HOW THEY GOT TO MY
HOUSE.
THEY WERE SO BRAVE.
AND THEY WERE SO GOOD.
AND I BROUGHT DOWN SOME TOYS
FROM MY GRANDSON'S TOY CHEST AND
I GAVE THEM SOME JUICE.
AND WE CALLED THEIR PARENTS.
THEY WERE VERY BRAVE AND VERY
GOOD.
AND I WAS AMAZED.
I WAS ASTOUNDED AT WHAT THEY
WERE TELLING ME.
>> THEY NOTICE EVERYTHING.
I KNOW YOU'RE A PSYCHOLOGIST BY
TRAINING, BUT YOU TALK ABOUT
BEING A GRANDFATHER.
THAT WAS THE GRANDFATHER THAT
WAS YOU AT THAT MOMENT?
>> THAT'S WHAT TRAINED ME, BEING
A GRANDFATHER.
I FELT LIKE I WAS WITH MY
GRANDCHILDREN.
AND I WAS HAPPY WITH THEM.
THAT'S WHAT TRAINED ME.
MY GRANDDAUGHTER AND MY
GRANDSON, AND THEY WERE WITH ME.
I FELT COMFORTABLE.
THEY WERE VERY SWEET, AND THEY
CALMED DOWN A LITTLE, BUT THEY
WERE SO -- THEY KEPT REPEATING
THAT THEY CAN'T GO BACK TO THE
SCHOOL BECAUSE THEY DON'T HAVE A
TEACHER.
>> AND THEIR GRIEVING IS GOING
TO BE HARD FOR ADULTS TO
UNDERSTAND.
IT WILL BE DIFFERENT, IT MAY BE
MORE INTENSE.
IT WILL BE DIFFERENT.
WHAT MESSAGE DO YOU HAVE FOR
THOSE CHILDREN WHO CAME ONTO
YOUR YARD?
>> I WANT TO BE REUNITED WITH
THEM.
I WANT TO SEE THOSE CHILDREN.
AND I WANT TO TELL THEM HOW GOOD
AND BRAVE AND STRONG THEY ARE.
I WANT TO TELL THEIR PARENTS
THAT.
AND I WANT TO TELL THEM THAT I
WANT TO BE THEIR FRIEND AND I
WANT TO READ TO THEM.
I WANT TO GIVE THEM SOMETHING
SPECIAL FOR CHRISTMAS.
I WANT TO BE THEIR FRIEND.
I WANT THEM TO SEE ME IN LIGHT
INSTEAD OF DARKNESS.
AS I SAW THEM.
I LOVE THEIR PARENTS.
I HOPE THEY'LL CALL ME BECAUSE I
WANT TO SEE THOSE CHILDREN.
THEY WERE VERY GOOD CHILDREN.
AND THEN SOMETHING HAPPENED WITH
ONE OF THE BOYS, OUT OF THE
GRIEF AND CARNAGE, AND HE
STOPPED AND HE BECAME VERY
COMPOSED.
AND ALL OF A SUDDEN, HE STOPS
AND HE LOOKED AT ME AND HE SAID,
JUST SAYING, YOUR HOUSE IS VERY
SMALL.
AND I THOUGHT -- I THOUGHT, WHAT
A BRIGHT, WONDERFUL BOY.
AND HE JUST BROUGHT TO ALL OF US
A RESPITE, RESPITE FROM ALL OF
THIS DARKNESS.
YOU KNOW WHAT, I WANT TO SEE
THESE KIDS.
I HOPE THEIR PARENTS WILL CALL
ME.
I WANT TO JUST PUT MY ARMS
AROUND THEM AND TELL THEM THAT I
LOVE THEM.
I WANT THE CHILDREN TO BE THE
BASIS FOR OUR SOLUTION.
THAT'S WHAT I WANT.
>> I HOPE THAT THEY ARE, AND I
HOPE YOU'LL BE THAT WHEN THEY
REMEMBER THAT DAY, YOU'LL BE THE
BEACON OF LIGHT FOR THEM, TOO.
THANK YOU SO MUCH, GENE.
>> I SO APPRECIATE YOU LETTING
ME TELL MY STORY.
>> WE APPRECIATE YOU TELLING IT.
>>> "OUTFRONT" NEXT, HAS THE
WORLD CHANGED, AND PERHAPS IN A
WAY FOR THIS COUNTRY FOR THE
BETTER?
JOHN AVALON LOOKS AT HOW FINALLY
THERE MIGHT BE A REASONABLE
CONVERSATION IN THIS COUNTRY
ABOUT GUNS.
>>> AND THE HERO PRINCIPAL FROM
THE POINT OF SHVIEW OF THE FRIES
WHO KNEW HER.
TO DRIVE A JEEP GRAND CHEROKEE,
TELL THEM
IT'S LIKE BEING NESTLED
IN AN EIGHT-WAY, ADJUSTABLE,
HEATED AND VENTILATED SEAT
SURROUNDED BY A 500-WATT
SOUND SYSTEM
WHILE FLOATING ON A SUSPENSION
MADE OF BILLOWY CLOUDS.
OR YOU COULD JUST HAND THEM
YOUR KEYS.
♪
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA THINS
PACK THE BIG TASTE
OF GRANOLA AND DARK CHOCOLATE
INTO ONE PERFECT SQUARE,
UNDER 100 CALORIES.
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA THINS.
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
>>> IN THE AFTERMATH OF THE
NEWTOWN TRAGEDY, THERE'S GROWING
DEMAND FOR TIGHTING CONTROL ON
GUNS.
AN ABC/WASHINGTON POST POLL
FOUND A BIG SHIFT, THE NUMBER OF
PEOPLE WHO SAY THEY STRONGLY
SUPPORT STRICTER GUN CONTROL
LAWS WENT UP BY FIVE POINTS
WHILE THE NUMBER WHO STRONGLY
OPPOSE WENT DOWN FIVE POINTS.
AS I RECALL AFTER THE SHOOTING
IN AURORA, COLORADO, THEY DIDN'T
SEE SUCH A BIG SHIFT.
AFTER SOME MASS SHOOTINGS, YOU
DO.
THIS TIME, IT'S A BIGGER MOVE.
THE QUESTION IS WILL IT GAIN
MORE MOMENTUM, AND WILL
WASHINGTON DO ANYTHING ABOUT IT?
JOHN HAS BEEN LOOKING AT IT.
LAWMAKERS FROM BOTH SIDES OF THE
PARTY, EVEN STAUNCH MEMBERS,
STAUNCHLY BACKED BY THE NRA ARE
UNITED IN THEIR GRIEF AND SAY
THEY WANT CHANGE TO HAPPEN, BUT
WILL IT?
>> ERIN, SOMETIMES IT TAKES
TRAGEDY TO MAKE US CONFRONT
REALITY.
YOU ARE STARTING TO SEE
POLITICIANS ON BOTH SIDES OF THE
AISLE SAY MAYBE NOW IS NOT THE
TIME TO RELY ON IDEOLOGY OR
PARTISAN POLITICS PUT TO START
TAKING A LONG LOOK AT THE LAWS
THAT EXIST AROUND GUNS.
NOT INFRINGING ON THE SECOND
AMENDMENT, BUT TAKING A LOOK AT
WHAT REASONABLE RESTRICTIONS CAN
BE PUT IN PLACE.
IN THE LAST 24 HOURS, TWO
LEADING SOUTHERN DEMOCRATIC
LEADERS, JOEL MANCHIN AND MARK
WARNER, SAID THIS EVENT HAS
CHANGED THEM AND THEY'RE OPEN TO
NEW SOLUTIONS.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT WHAT M
MANCHIN TOLD CHRISTINE AMANPOUR.
>> WHO WOULD THINK THAT CHILDREN
IN AMERICA OR ANYONE WOULD BE
SLAUGHTERED?
IT CHANGED ME.
I DON'T KNOW OF ANYONE WHO GOES
HUNTING WITH AN ASSAULT RIFLE.
I DON'T KNOW PEOPLE WHO NEED 10,
20, 30-ROUND CLIPS.
>> I BELIEVE EVERY AMERICAN HAS
A SECOND AMENDMENT RIGHT AND THE
ABILITY TO HUNT IS PART OF OUR
CULTURE.
I HAD AN NRA RATING OF AN "A,"
BUT YOU KNOW, ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
>> SO, ERIN, THAT'S THE
BEGINNING OF WHAT MAY BE A
SIGNIFICANT SHIFT IN EVOLUTION
ON THIS ISSUE.
JUST OPENING UP THIS
CONVERSATION AGAIN.
AS YOU KNOW, THE NATION HAD AN
ASSAULT KNOW, THE NATION HAD AN
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN WHICH
EXPIRED IN 2004.
AND THAT'S ONE OF THE THINGS
THAT SENATORS ARE TALKING ABOUT
LOOKING AT.
SO THE FACT THAT THESE TWO
SENATORS WITH A RATINGS FROM THE
NRA ARE SAYING THEY'RE OPEN TO
THIS KIND OF A CONVERSATION IS
REALLY SIGNIFICANT.
>> ALL RIGHT, JOHN AVLON, THANK
YOU VERY MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> WELL, AS THE RESIDENTS OF
NEWTOWN MOURN THE LOSS OF
FRIENDS AND FAMILY, ONE OF THE
THINGS THAT HELPS KEEP THEM
GOING IS CELEBRATING THOSE WHO
ARE BRAVE AMIDST THE CHAOS.
SANDY HOOK PRINCIPAL DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG WAS ONE OF THEM.
OUR NEXT GUEST HAS LIVED IN THIS
COMMUNITY FOR ALMOST 20 YEARS.
ALL THREE OF HER CHILDREN
ATTENDED SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY,
AND SHE BECAME FRIENDS WITH MANY
OF THE TEACHER THERE'S,
INCLUDING DAWN HOCK STRUNG.
MIRANDA IS HERE TONIGHT TO
REMEMBER.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
I KNOW THREE CHILDREN.
ONE OF YOUR CHILDREN HAS FRIENDS
WHO HAVE LOST SIBLINGS?
>> YES.
>> LET ME ASK YOU ABOUT DAWN.
YOU KNEW HER WELL.
YOU WORKED WITH HER FOR A WHILE.
>> I DIDN'T KNOW HER WELL.
I WORKED WITH HER BECAUSE I WAS
VERY ACTIVE AS MOM IN THE
SCHOOL.
YES, MY YOUNGEST DAUGHTER, WHEN
SHE WAS THERE, DAWN WAS THERE AT
THE SAME TIME.
YEAH, DAWN WAS AN UNUSUAL
PRINCIPAL.
SHE DIDN'T HAVE THAT FORMALITY
THAT A LOT OF, YOU KNOW,
ADMINISTRATORS MIGHT HAVE.
SHE HAD THIS RADIANT SMILE.
SHE WAS ALWAYS ABOUT FUN AND
WARMTH.
AND, YOU KNOW, YOU KIND OF FELT
LIKE YOU COULD JUST GIVE HER A
HUG AS SOON AS YOU MET HER.
SHE HAD A RARE QUALITY.
>> HOW DO YOU -- HOW DO YOU
FEEL, AND HOW DOES THIS TOWN
FEEL, JUST BEING HERE?
IT IS A PICTURE-PERFECT LITTLE
TOWN.
AND IT'S SMALL.
AND IT FEELS LIKE EVERYBODY HERE
WOULD KNOW EVERYBODY ELSE.
>> YEAH, WELL, WE ARE ALL
CONNECTED HERE.
YEAH.
I FELT A LITTLE BIT CONFLICTED
TONIGHT ABOUT COMING OUT.
I WANTED TO MAKE SURE THAT IT
WAS THE RIGHT THING TO DO.
BUT I FELT LIKE COY HAVE AN
OPPORTUNITY TO TALK A LITTLE BIT
ABOUT THE COLLECTIVE GRIEF THAT
WE'RE FEELING AS A COMMUNITY.
YOU KNOW, WE FEEL -- WE FEEL
NUMB.
WE'RE CARRYING OUR GRIEF AROUND
WITH US.
WE HAVE THE THOUGHTS OF THE
PARENTS WHO LOST THEIR CHILDREN
IN OUR MINDS ALL THE TIME.
AND IT'S HARD.
EVERYTHING HAS STOPPED NOW.
IT'S HARD -- IT'S HARD TO GET ON
WITH YOUR ROUTINE.
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE, ACTUALLY.
I HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE TO MAKE
COFFEE WITHOUT FORGETTING WHAT
I'M DOING HALFWAY THROUGH.
BUT, YOU KNOW, I JUST WANT TO
GET THE MESSAGE OUT TO MY
FRIENDS AND NEIGHBORS,
ESPECIALLY THE ONES WHO ARE
GRIEVING THE MOST, WHO HAVE LOST
LOVED ONES THAT WE'RE IN THIS
TOGETHER AND THAT THERE IS SO
MUCH GOOD IN THE WORLD, AND THAT
WE'RE GOING TO HOLD ON TO IT
TOGETHER.
>> I KNOW THAT YOU WERE TELLING
A PERSONAL STORY JUST ABOUT HOW
IT'S HARD TO SLEEP.
>> YEAH.
>> BUT WHEN YOU DOZED OFF A
LITTLE BIT LAST NIGHT AND WOKE
UP, YOU HAD TO WAKE YOUR HUSBAND
UP JUST TO SEE IF IT WAS REAL.
>> I WOKE HIM UP AND I SAID TO
HIM IS THIS REALLY HAPPENING?
AND THAT'S A LINE THAT HAS BEEN
RUNNING THROUGH MY HEAD.
AND I MENTIONED THAT TO FRIENDS
OF MINE, AND THEY ALL COULD
REALLY RELATE TO THAT.
IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE IT.
IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE WHEN
PRESIDENT OBAMA GAVE THAT
BEAUTIFUL SPEECH LAST NIGHT AND
HE LISTED THE MASSACRES THAT
HAVE HAPPENED IN OUR COUNTRY,
THE TRAGIC EVENTS.
AND AT THE END OF IT CAME THE
NAME OF OUR LITTLE TOWN THAT NO
ONE ELSE USED TO, YOU KNOW -- I
USED TO HAVE TO EXPLAIN WHERE IT
WAS.
THAT WAS SHOCKING.
>> AND YOU DON'T WANT IT TO BE
THAT WAY.
AND YOU DON'T WANT IT TO BE
COLUMBINE.
>> EXACTLY.
I DON'T WANT PEOPLE TO ASSOCIATE
THE NAME OF OUR TOWN WITH THIS
HORRIBLE TRAGEDY.
OUR TOWN IS SO MUCH MORE THAN
THAT.
IT'S A REALLY SPECIAL PLACE
WHERE PARENTS ARE SO COMMITTED
TO THEIR CHILDREN'S EDUCATION
AND BRINGING THEM UP WELL.
AND MY KIDS HAVE SUCH WONDERFUL
MEMORIES OF SANDY HOOK.
IT'S A HUGE PART OF THEIR
CHILDHOOD.
HAVE I WONDERFUL MEMORIES THERE
AND I WANT THEM TO BE ABLE TO
CONTINUE TO HAVE THOSE MEMORIES
AND NOT THINK OF IT AS THE CRIME
SCENE.
>> THIS IS A TOUGH QUESTION TO
ASK GIVEN MY ROLE, BUT THE
MEDIA, WHEN I WALK AROUND HERE,
I SEE A LOT OF PEOPLE LIKE ME.
WE'RE TRYING COVER THIS STORY,
BUT I KNOW THAT WE'RE MAKING IT
HARD TOO IN SOME WAYS FOR YOU.
>> YEAH.
THANK YOU FOR ASKING THAT, ERIN.
YOU KNOW, I CAME DOWN A COUPLE
OF DAYS AGO.
I CAME DOWN TO THE CENTER OF
SANDY HOOK HERE WHEN THE MEDIA
WAS HERE.
AND I KEPT BUMPING INTO FRIENDS,
AND FRIENDS OF FRIENDS, AND WE
WOULD HOLD EACH OTHER AND
EMBRACE EACH OTHER AND COME
TOGETHER.
AND THAT FEELS VITAL RIGHT NOW.
AND WHEN I CAME HERE TONIGHT, I
DIDN'T SEE ANYBODY I KNEW.
AND WE REALLY FEEL THAT THE
NATION FEELS OUR PAIN AND WANTS
TO REACH OUT AND WANTS TO BE
HERE WITH US.
AND THAT MEANS A GREAT DEAL.
ON THE OTHER HAND, IT'S HARD TO
NOT BE ABLE TO GET -- TO DRIVE
AROUND YOUR OWN TOWN, WHEN
REALLY WHAT WE NEED IS TO BE
TOGETHER.
>> MIRANDA, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
>> WE APPRECIATE YOUR TAKING THE
TIME TO SHARE WITH US.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> AND UP NEXT, A TOWN FOREVER
CHANGED.
ADDING A FRIEND...
♪
...COULD END
WITH ADDING A CLOSE FRIEND.
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
FIVE DAYS LATER,
I HAD A MASSIVE HEART ATTACK.
BAYER ASPIRIN WAS THE FIRST
THING THE EMTS GAVE ME.
NOW, I'M ON
A BAYER ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Male Announcer ] BE SURE
TO TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE YOU BEGIN
AN ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Woman ]
LEARN FROM MY STORY.
>>> FINALLY TONIGHT, A NEW
NORMAL IN NEWTOWN.
THE LIBRARY, THE GENERAL STORE,
THE DINER THAT FILLS WITH KIDS
AFTER HIGH SCHOOL BASKETBALL
GAMES.
THE HALLMARKS OF A
PICTURE-PERFECT NEW ENGLAND
TOWN, NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
DONNA MOVED HERE 15 YEARS AGO TO
RAISE HER THREE KIDS.
>> THIS IS A TOWN WHERE I DIDN'T
LOCK MY DOORS, I DIDN'T LOCK MY
CAR DOORS, MY HOUSE WAS OPEN.
MY KIDS RAN BACK AND FORTH TO
EACH OTHER'S HOUSES.
NEVER FELT UNSAFE.
>> Reporter: AND IT WAS SAFE.
JUST ONE MURDER IN THE PAST
DECADE.
ON FRIDAY, THAT CHANGED.
20 SCHOOL CHILDREN GUN DOWN IN
THEIR ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
CLASSROOMS.
FOUR OF THEIR TEACHERS, THEIR
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST, AND THEIR
PRINCIPAL, ALL GONE.
NEWS OF A SHOOTING IN THIS TOWN
WAS MET WITH DISBELIEF.
>> ALL I COULD THINK IS MAYBE IT
WAS A HUNTING ACCIDENT BECAUSE
NOTHING LIKE THIS WOULD EVER