>>> AS YOU CAN IMAGINE, A CLOUD
OF GRIEF HANGS OVER NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, TODAY.
THE COMMUNITY BEGINS THE FIRST
OF MORE THAN TWO DOZEN
HEART-WRENCHING GOOD-BYES.
FUNERALS FOR TWO OF THE
6-YEAR-OLDS KILLED IN THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL MASSACRE ARE
BEING HELD TODAY.
I'M SUZANNE MALVEAUX IN ATLANTA
WITH "NEWSROOM" SPECIAL COVERAGE
AS NEWTOWN REMEMBERS.
>> Reporter: AND I'M WOLF
BLITZER HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THE FUNERALS WILL CONTINUE FOR
DAYS AS THE 20 CHILDREN, THE 6
TEACHERS ARE LAID TO REST.
ALL THIS FOLLOWS A VERY MOVING
AND EMOTIONAL SERVICE LAST
NIGHT.
♪
IT INCLUDES A PRAYER SUNG BY A
RABBI, READINGS FROM THE BIBLE
AND THE KORAN, PRAYERS FROM
CHRISTIAN LEADERS AND A PROMISE
FROM PRESIDENT OBAMA.
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS, I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT, TO MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS, TO PARENTS
AND EDUCATORS IN AN EFFORT AIMED
AT PREVENTING MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS.
>> TONIGHT THE CROWD AT THE
PRAYER SERVICE GAVE A STANDING
OVATION TO THE FIRST RESPONDERS,
THOSE WHO ANSWERED THE CALL AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE WANT TO UPDATE YOU ON THE
INVESTIGATION AS WELL, THE
DEVELOPMENTS IN THE AFTERMATH OF
THE TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN.
HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW NOW.
POLICE SAY THAT TWO PEOPLE SHOT
AND WOUNDED IN THE RAMPAGE ARE
RECOVERING.
INITIAL REPORTS INDICATED ONLY
ONE PERSON WHO WAS WOUNDED HAD
SURVIVED.
NOW, INVESTIGATORS CONTINUE
PIECING TOGETHER EXACTLY WHAT
HAPPENED.
NOW, THEY SAY THEY'RE NOT GOING
TO STOP UNTIL THEY'VE
INTERVIEWED EVERY WITNESS AND
ANALYZED EVERY PIECE OF EVIDENCE
INCLUDING EACH ROUND OF
AMMUNITION.
FACULTY MEMBERS ARE MEETING
TODAY.
SCHOOLS IN NEWTOWN WILL REOPEN
TOMORROW.
BUT THE CLASSES AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY, THEY'RE GOING TO BE
SUSPENDED UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE.
WE ARE ALSO EXPECTING ANOTHER
BRIEFING FROM CONNECTICUT
POLICE, COULD START ANY MINUTE
NOW.
WE'LL BE MONITORING THAT, GOING
TO BRING IT TO YOU LIVE AS SOON
AS THAT STARTS AS WELL.
>> Reporter: LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE WHO'S BEEN BRIEFING
ROERTDS, HE'LL BE BRIEFING ONCE
AGAIN.
THEY WERE JUST 6 YEARS OLD,
THEIR LIVES CUT SHORT BY A
HORRIFIC ACT OF VIOLENCE.
NEXT HOUR FAMILIES FACE WHAT
SEEMS UNBEARABLE AS THEY SAY
GOOD-BYE TO TWO FIRST GRADERS
KILLED IN THE SHOOTING AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
FUNERALS ARE SET TO BEGIN FOR
JACK PINTO AND NOAH POZNER.
JACK LOVED SPORTS, BASEBALL,
WRESTLING, BUT FOOTBALL WAS HIS
FAVORITE.
NOAH LOVED PLAYING WITH HIS
SIBLINGS, ESPECIALLY HIS TWIN
SISTER.
JACK AND NOAH ARE TWO OF THE 20
CHILDREN WHO DIED.
AT LAST NIGHT'S PRAYER SERVICE,
PRESIDENT OBAMA CALLED OUT EACH
ONE BY NAME.
>> LET THE LITTLE CHILDREN COME
TO ME, JESUS SAID, AND DO NOT
HINDER THEM.
FOR TO SUCH BELONGS THE KINGDOM
OF HEAVEN.
CHARLOTTE, DANIEL, OLIVIA,
JOSEPHINE, ANA, DYLAN,
MADELEINE, CATHERINE, CHASE,
JESSE, JAMES, GRACE, EMILIE,
JACK, NOAH, CAROLINE, JESSICA,
BENJAM
BENJAMIN, AVIELLE, ALLISON.
GOD HAS CALLED THEM ALL HOME.
FOR THOSE OF US WHO REMAIN, LET
US FIND THE STRENGTH TO CARRY ON
AND MAKE OUR COUNTRY WORTHY OF
THEIR MEMORY.
>> I CERTAINLY HOPE WE DO JUST
THAT.
THIS IS A TRAGEDY BEYOND BELIEF
OR UNDERSTANDING.
PEOPLE WANT TO KNOW HOW THIS
COULD HAVE HAPPENED.
WHAT COULD HAVE DRIVEN A YOUNG
MAN TO KILL HIS OWN MOTHER AND
THEN GUN DOWN 20 YOUNG CHILDREN
AND 6 ADULTS?
AND THERE ARE QUESTIONS THAT ARE
RAISED ABOUT HIS OWN CHILDHOOD,
HIS FAMILY LIFE.
I WANT TO BRING IN DEBORAH
FEYERICK IN NEWTOWN.
DEB, WE'VE BEEN LEARNING MORE
THINGS ABOUT THE GUNMAN IN THE
DAYS PRIOR, ADAM LANZA, LEADING
UP TO THIS MASSACRE.
WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT
SPECIFICALLY SOME COMPUTERS THAT
WERE SMASHED, THINGS THAT
INVESTIGATORS ARE LOOKING AT TO
TRY TO COME UP WITH SOME CLUES
OR SOME ANSWERS?
>> Reporter: YOU KNOW, IT IS SO
IMPORTANT FOR INVESTIGATORS TO
TRY TO PIECE TOGETHER EVERYTHING
THAT HAPPENED IN THE DAYS
LEADING UP TO THE CRIME.
WHAT WE DO WANT TO DO IS SHOW
YOU THE HOME.
THIS IS WHERE THE TRAGEDY TOOK
PLACE.
IT IS STILL CONSIDERED A CRIME
SCENE.
YOU CAN SEE IT'S SURROUNDED BY
CRIME TAPE.
INVESTIGATORS, THE POLICE, WILL
HOLD ON TO THIS HOME UNTIL
THEY'VE GONE THROUGH IT WITH A
FINE-TOOTH COMB.
WE DO KNOW THAT FIREARMS WERE A
LARGE PART OF NANCY LANZA'S
LIFE.
SHE'S DESCRIBED AS A COUNTRY
GIRL, A GUN ENTHUSIAST WHO
REALLY LIKED TO SHOOT.
WE ARE TOLD BY THE ATF, THE
ALCOHOL, TOBACCO, FIREARMS
BUREAU, THEY'RE THE ONES TO
HANDLE THE GUNS, THE WEAPONS,
THE FIREARMS.
THAT, IN FACT, ADAM LANZA AND
HIS MOM DID VISIT A GUN RANGE IN
THE DAYS LEADING UP TO THE
SHOOTING.
NOW, AGAIN, SHE WAS A GUN
ENTHUSIAST.
IT APPEARS SHE WAS TEACHING HER
SON HOW TO SHOOT.
WE DON'T KNOW WHY.
AND THAT'S ONE OF THE THINGS
THAT'S UNDER INVESTIGATION.
BUT ON FRIDAY, HER SON GOT HOLD
OF AT LEAST THREE OF THOSE
FIREARMS.
HE KILLED HER EARLY IN THE
MORNING BEFORE SETTING OUT AND
LEAVING THIS HOME TO GO ON THE
RAMPAGE AT THE SCHOOL, ACCORDING
TO A REPORT IN "THE WALL STREET
JOURNAL," WHEN HE WAS A FRESHMAN
AT THE LOCAL HIGH SCHOOL BACK IN
2007, HE WAS APPOINTED A SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST, AND THEY WERE VERY
CONCERNED NOT THAT HE WAS A
DANGER THAT, IN FACT, HE WAS SO
VULNERABLE THAT HE HIMSELF COULD
BECOME A TARGET.
SO ALL OF THAT IS BEING
INVESTIGATED.
THE COMPUTER, SUZANNE, THAT YOU
MENTIONED, THAT, TOO, THERE ARE
REPORTS THAT THE HARD DRIVE WAS
BROKEN, THAT IT WAS SMASHED.
THE QUESTION, DID THAT HAPPEN
BEFORE HE SNAPPED, OR WAS THAT
SOMETHING THAT HE DID ONCE HE
DETERMINED THAT HE WAS GOING TO
GO ON THIS SHOOTING SPREE?
SO INVESTIGATORS REALLY HOLDING
THE INFORMATION PRETTY CLOSE
JUST SO THAT THEY CAN PIECE IT
TOGETHER AND TRY TO RECREATE THE
FINAL MOMENTS LEADING UP TO THIS
SLAUGHTER OF INNOCENCE, SUZANNE.
>> DEB, DO WE HAVE ANY IDEA, ANY
SENSE OF, AGAIN, THE SHOOTER'S
MENTAL STATE OR WHAT HE WAS
GOING THROUGH, OR IS THERE ANY
MORE INFORMATION REGARDING
MOTIVE OR HIS CONNECTION TO THE
SCHOOL?
>> Reporter: WE DO KNOW THAT THE
DETECTIVES ARE QUESTIONING A
FORMER DOCTOR, FORMER TEACHERS,
ANYBODY WHO MAY HAVE COME IN
CONTACT WITH HIM.
WHAT IS SO FASCINATING ABOUT
THIS PARTICULAR CASE, SUZANNE,
IS THAT USUALLY WHEN THIS KIND
OF TRAGEDY HAPPENS, THE MOTIVE
OF THE GUNMAN, IT'S ABLE TO BE
PIECED TOGETHER VERY, VERY
QUICKLY.
BUT IN THIS CASE, IT SEEMS AS IF
HE WAS SO REMOVED FROM SOCIETY
IN SUCH A FUNDAMENTAL WAY THAT
THERE'S SO LITTLE INFORMATION
THAT'S COMING OUT RIGHT NOW.
AND AGAIN, THAT IS PART OF THE
PUZZLE.
AND THAT IS ONE OF THE THINGS
INVESTIGATORS ARE LOOKING INTO
IS TO WHETHER HE WAS SO ISOLATED
AND WHETHER THE REASON FOR THAT
WAS BECAUSE HE WAS ON THIS
DANGEROUS PATH, SUZANNE.
>> DEB, DO WE HAVE ANY IDEA
WHETHER OR NOT HE HAD A
CONNECTION TO THE SCHOOL AT ALL?
THERE WERE CONFLICTING REPORTS
ABOUT WHETHER OR NOT HIS MOTHER
EVER TAUGHT THERE, AND THEN THAT
WAS DISMISSED.
DO WE KNOW WHAT THE ASSOCIATION
WAS WITH THE SCHOOL?
HAD HE BEEN A STUDENT AT THAT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL BACK A WHILE?
>> Reporter: YEAH.
YOU KNOW, WE HAVE BEEN SEARCHING
FOR THAT ANSWER AS TO WHY HE
DECIDED TO PICK THAT SCHOOL.
IT'S REALLY UNCLEAR.
ALL I CAN TELL YOU IS, YOU KNOW,
THIS HOME THAT HE MOVED INTO, HE
WOULD HAVE BEEN ABOUT 6 OR 7,
THE SAME AGE AS THE CHILDREN
THAT HE WENT AFTER IN THAT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
HE WAS AT A LOCAL HIGH SCHOOL
HERE.
THERE ARE REPORTS THAT HE WENT
TO A LOCAL COLLEGE AND TOOK SOME
COURSES THERE.
BUT AS TO WHY THAT SCHOOL, NO,
IT'S NOT CLEAR.
AND WHEN YOU GET INSIDE THE MIND
OF SOMEBODY LIKE HIM, HE COULD
HAVE READ A REFERENCE.
HE COULD HAVE KNOWN SOMEBODY
THAT WENT TO THAT SCHOOL.
IT'S JUST SO UNCLEAR RIGHT NOW.
AND THAT'S WHAT THE DETECTIVES
AND ALL THE POLICE ARE TRYING TO
PIECE TOGETHER.
>> AND DEB, FINALLY, WE
UNDERSTAND THAT ADAM'S AUNT,
MARSHA, TOLD AN AFFILIATE THAT
SHE OWNED HER GUNS FOR
SELF-DEFENSE, BUT SHE NEVER FELT
THREATENED.
WHY DID SHE EVEN HAVE THIS
COLLECTION OF GUNS, AND DO WE
KNOW HOW ACCESSIBLE THEY WERE TO
HER SON?
>> Reporter: YOU KNOW, THERE
HAVE BEEN REPORTS, AND PEOPLE
WHO KNEW NANCY LANZA, THAT SHE
SIMPLY SORT OF LIKED SHOOTING,
THAT SHE WAS A GUN ENTHUSIAST,
SORT OF A COUNTRY GIRL.
YOU DRIVE OUT HERE, AND YOU
REALLY DO FEEL LIKE YOU'RE
PRETTY MUCH OUT IN THE COUNTRY.
THE REASONS AS TO WHY SHE HAD
SUCH HIGH-POWERED WEAPONS, A LOT
OF LEGITIMATE GUN OWNERS HAVE
THAT KIND OF WEAPONRY.
THAT'S JUST WHAT THEY DO.
THAT'S WHAT THEY HAVE.
WHETHER SHE FELT SHE WAS AT RISK
FROM HIM, IF SHE WERE, THE
QUESTION IS IS WOULD SHE HAVE
LEFT THOSE GUNS UNLOCKED?
WHY WEREN'T THEY LOCKED UP SO
THAT, IN FACT, IF HE WAS A
DANGER EITHER TO HER OR TO
SOMEONE ELSE, WHY WEREN'T THOSE
GUNS PROPERLY HOLSTERED,
BASICALLY, PROPERLY LOCKED UP?
>> DEB FEYERICK, THANK YOU SO
MUCH.
APPRECIATE IT.
STILL A LOT OF UNANSWERED
QUESTIONS.
FAMILIES ARE CALLING THE
TEACHERS AT THAT SCHOOL, SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, HEROES.
YOU CAN IMAGINE WHY.
THEY PROTECTED THEIR CHILDREN
FROM THAT MASSACRE, FROM THE
GUNMAN'S ASSAULT.
AND OUR OWN ANDERSON COOPER, HE
ACTUALLY GOT A CHANCE TO SPEAK
TO ONE OF THOSE TEACHERS, JANET
VOLLMER, ABOUT WHAT IT WAS
ACTUALLY LIKE INSIDE THE
CLASSROOM.
>> Reporter: EXPLAIN AGAIN, YOU
HEARD -- YOU KNEW SOMETHING WAS
GOING WRONG.
HOW?
>> WELL, I MEAN, WE WERE IN OUR
CLASSROOM.
AND WE HEARD WHAT SOUNDED LIKE
GUNSHOTS, NOISES.
>> Reporter: YOU HEARD IT ON
THE --
>> THERE WAS A LOUDSPEAKER --
>> Reporter: THE PA SYSTEM.
>> THE PA SYSTEM WAS NOT WORKING
THE WAY IT NORMALLY IS BECAUSE
YOU DON'T USUALLY HEAR THINGS
UNLESS SOMEONE IS MAKING AN
ANNOUNCEMENT.
THERE WERE NOISES THAT DIDN'T
SOUND CORRECT.
SO THERE WASN'T ANYONE TELLING
US IT WAS A DRILL.
WE JUST THOUGHT SOMETHING WAS
NOT RIGHT.
WE TOOK THE CHILDREN INTO WHAT
WE CALL A LOCKDOWN.
AND WE GO TO A CERTAIN PLACE IN
THE ROOM.
WE PULL THE BLINDS DOWN.
WE LOCK THE CLASSROOM DOORS.
AND WE COVER THE WINDOW OUT THE
DOOR.
>> Reporter: SO THIS IS
SOMETHING YOU HAD PRACTICED?
>> ABOUT A MONTH OR SO, DAWN
MADE SURE THAT WE DO THAT.
YOU KNOW, WE'D GO TO A SAFE
PLACE.
AND TYPICALLY WHETHER IT'S A
DRILL, THEY TELL US, OKAY, AND
THEN WE EVEN EXITED THE BUILDING
FOLLOWING A CERTAIN PATH.
AND IF THERE WAS AN EMERGENCY,
WE'D GO DOWN TO THE SANDY HOOK
FIREHOUSE AND GATHER THERE,
WHICH IS WHAT WE DID THAT DAY.
SO, YOU KNOW, WE KNEW THAT.
>> Reporter: BUT YOU SAT THE
KIDS DOWN --
>> WE SAT IN THE CUBBY AREA AWAY
FROM THE DOOR SO NO ONE COULD
SEE US AND READ THEM A STORY,
TALKED TO THEM.
YOU KNOW, THEY KEPT SAYING HOW
COME WE'RE HERE SO LONG?
I SAID, WELL, IT WILL BE A
LITTLE LONGER.
AND THEY'RE 5.
YOU TELL THEM WHATEVER YOU DO TO
KEEP THEM SAFE AND KEEP THEM
CALM.
>> Reporter: THIS IS WHAT I'VE
BEEN THINKING ABOUT ALL WEEKEND,
THOUGH.
I MEAN, THE COURAGE FOR YOU TO
BE ABLE TO JUST SIT THERE AND
READ A STORY AND KEEP THEM CALM.
>> I THINK THE ADRENALINE KICKS
IN, AND YOU DO WHAT YOU HAVE TO
DO.
I MEAN, THERE WAS TWO OTHER
PEOPLE IN THE ROOM THAT WERE
HELPING ME WITH, YOU KNOW,
PULLING DOWN THE BLINDS AND
THAT.
I WAS FOCUSED ON THE KIDS.
YOU KNOW, JUST KEEPING THEM
SAFE.
I'M NOT ABOUT TO TELL THEM THAT
I THINK SOMETHING IS VERY BAD OR
VERY WRONG.
SO WE WAITED AND WAITED.
YOU KNOW, IT SEEMED LIKE A VERY
LONG TIME.
AND MAYBE IT WAS 20 MINUTES, A
HALF AN HOUR, I'M NOT SURE.
THERE WERE KNOCKS AT THE DOOR.
IT WAS POLICE, SOMEONE, TELLING
US THAT WE HAD TO LEAVE.
DIDN'T WANT TO OPEN THE DOOR AT
FIRST, BUT WE DID.
YOU KNOW, THEY SAID, HAVE THE
CHILDREN WALK, HOLD HANDS, COVER
THEIR EYES IF THEY COULD
BECAUSE, YOU KNOW, HE DIDN'T SAY
WHY.
HE JUST SAID, HAVE THEM COVER
THEIR EYES.
WELL, AT 5, COVERING YOUR EYES
AND WALKING ISN'T SO EASY.
SO I JUST HAD THEM LOOK TOWARDS
THE WALL.
AND WE WENT DOWN THE HALL AND
OUT OF THE BUILDING.
AND WE GOT ON THE SIDEWALK.
AND I SAID, BOYS AND GIRLS,
REMEMBER THE ADVENTURE WE HAD?
WE ALL WALKED TO THE FIREHOUSE?
WE'RE GOING TO DO THAT NOW
AGAIN.
>> AS THE ENTIRE NATION GRAPPLES
TO COME TO TERMS WITH WHAT
HAPPENED IN THIS SMALL
CONNECTICUT TOWN, WE ALSO WANT
TO TAKE A LOOK AT HOW OTHER
COUNTRIES APPROACH GUN CONTROL.
OUR FAREED ZAKARIA IS GOING TO
WEIGH IN ON THAT AS WELL.
>> Reporter: ALSO, WE'RE
STANDING BY, JUST WANT TO REMIND
OUR VIEWERS FOR A NEWS
CONFERENCE.
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE WILL BE
GIVING US ALL THE LATEST ON
THEIR INVESTIGATION, WHAT THEY
CAN SHOW US.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT LIVE PICTURES,
THE MICROPHONES ARE SET UP.
AND WE WILL HAVE ALL THAT
INFORMATION FOR YOU.
YOU'LL SEE IT LIVE RIGHT HERE ON
CNN.
WE'RE GETTING TO KNOW MORE ABOUT
THE INNOCENT YOUNG KIDS, THE
TEACHERS ALSO, WHO WERE GUNNED
DOWN LIKE ANA MARQUEZ-GREENE, A
6-YEAR-OLD, WHO LOVED TO SING
AND PLAY PIANO.
>> ONE, TWO, THREE, READY AND
GO.
♪ COME NOW ALL MIGHTY KING
♪ HELP US GUIDE TO SEE
♪ HELP US
[ sniffs ] I HAVE A COLD.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
WELL, HAVING A TON OF LOCATIONS
DOESN'T HURT.
AND A SANTA TO BOOT!
[ chuckles ]
RIGHT, BABY.
OH, SIR.
THAT IS A CUSTOMER.
OH...SORRY ABOUT THAT.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
FEDEX OFFICE.
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
CONNECTING
TO THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
>>> AUTHORITIES TODAY ARE
EXAMINING ALL OF THE WEAPONRY,
EVERY SINGLE ROUND OF AMMUNITION
USED IN THE SANDY HOOK MASSACRE.
IT'S NOT EVEN CLEAR HOW MANY
SHOTS WERE FIRED, BUT POLICE
HAVE REVEALED WHAT TYPES OF GUNS
WERE ACTUALLY RECOVERED.
>> THE WEAPON THAT WAS UTILIZED
MOST OF THE TIME DURING THIS
HORRIFIC CRIME WAS IDENTIFIED AS
A BUSHMASTER AR-15 ASSAULT-TYPE
WEAPON.
IT HAD HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINES,
AND IN ADDITION TO THAT, THE
SUBJECT HAD IN HIS POSSESSION A
GLOCK .10 MILLIMETER, A SIG
SAUER .9 MILLIMETER.
BOTH WEAPONS HAD MULTIPLE
MAGAZINES AND AMMUNITION.
>> AND THEY WERE LEGALLY
PURCHASED AND REGISTERED TO
NANCY LANZA, THE MOTHER OF THE
SUSPECTED SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA.
AND NOW THE NATIONAL TRAGEDY,
THIS SENSELESS KILLING OF 20
LITTLE CHILDREN AND 6 ADULTS IS
REUNITING THE DEBATE ON GUNS IN
THIS COUNTRY.
I WANT TO BRING IN FAREED
ZAKARIA FROM NEW YORK.
FAREED, YOU LOOK AT WHAT HAPPENS
IN THIS COUNTRY, WE'VE GOT
SHOOTINGS IN CHURCHES, MALLS,
MOVIE THEATER, OTHER SCHOOLS,
EVEN THE ATTEMPTED MURDER OF
CONGRESSWOMAN GABBY GIFFORDS,
AND NOW SANDY HOOK.
WHEN PEOPLE LOOK AT WHAT HAPPENS
IN OUR COUNTRY, WHAT DO THEY
MAKE OF IT?
WHAT DO THEY THINK OF US?
>> WELL, FOR EVERYONE AROUND THE
WORLD, THIS ISSUE OF THE UNITED
STATES IS UTTERLY MYSTIFYING
BECAUSE WE KNOW WHAT WORKS.
THE UNITED STATES HAS 15 TO 20
TIMES AS MUCH GUN HOMICIDE AND
GUN SUICIDE, BY THE WAY, A LOT
OF IT IS SUICIDE, THAN ANY
ADVANCED COUNTRY IN THE WORLD.
WHAT'S DIFFERENT?
DO WE HAVE 15 TIMES AS MANY
MENTALLY DISTURBED PEOPLE?
HIGHLY UNLIKELY.
DO WE HAVE 15 TIMES MORE VIOLENT
TV OR VIDEO GAMES?
NO.
JAPAN HAS LOTS OF VIOLENT VIDEO
GAMES, AND THEY ACTUALLY HAVE
ASTONISHINGLY LOW GUN VIOLENCE.
THE BIG DIFFERENCE IS THAT WE
HAVE THESE INCREDIBLY LOOSE GUN
LAWS THAT MAKE ACCESS TO THE
KIND OF WEAPONS YOU JUST SHOWED,
SUZANNE, VERY EASY.
THE IDEA THAT PEOPLE -- THAT
ANYONE OTHER THAN LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIAL SHOULD HAVE
THAT KIND OF WEAPONRY,
SEMI-AUTOMATIC WEAPONRY, ASSAULT
RIFLES, IS REGARDED BY MOST OF
THE WORLD AS CRAZY.
IN AUSTRALIA, THE CONSERVATIVE
GOVERNMENT -- BY THE WAY, THIS
IS USUALLY A CONSERVATIVE
ISSUE -- CRACKED DOWN ON EASY
ACCESS TO GUNS AND SAW A 59%
DROP IN GUN HOMICIDE OVER THE --
>> FAREED, WHY DO YOU SUPPOSE
THIS IS A POLITICAL AND A
PARTISAN ISSUE IN THIS COUNTRY
AS OPPOSED TO OTHER COUNTRIES
THAT DON'T SEEM TO HAVE THAT
DIVISION OVER THIS ISSUE?
>> SOME OF IT DOES COME FROM A
TRADITION OF GUN OWNERSHIP FROM
A SUSPICION.
THE ORIGINAL REASON FOR THE
SECOND AMENDMENT WAS CONCERNS
THAT THE BRITISH GOVERNMENT WERE
TRYING TO STOP AMERICANS FROM
HAVING ARMS.
SOME OF IT IS CERTAINLY THAT.
BUT, LOOK, PLACES LIKE AUSTRALIA
HAVE SOME OF THAT
INDIVIDUALISTIC SPIRIT AS WELL.
I BELIEVE A LARGE PART OF IT IS
THAT OVER THE LAST 40 YEARS, WE
HAVE HAD A VERY WELL ORGANIZED,
WELL-FUNDED LOBBY THAT HAS MADE
IT IMPOSSIBLE TO HAVE ANY KIND
OF COMMON-SENSE REGULATION OF
GUNS.
WE REGULATE CARS MUCH MORE THAN
WE REGULATE GUNS IN THIS
COUNTRY.
WE REGULATE TOYS MORE THAN WE
REGULATE GUNS.
YOU HAVE -- GUNS CAN GO OFF IN
THIS COUNTRY WHEN THEY FALL,
WHEN THEY HIT THE FLOOR.
YOU'VE HAD EXAMPLES OF GUNS
GOING OFF, AND YOU CAN'T
REGULATE SO THAT THAT DOESN'T
HAPPEN.
YOU REGULATE TOYS NOT TO
MALFUNCTION LIKE THAT.
>> HOW DO YOU ACTUALLY DEAL WITH
THAT POWERFUL LOBBY, THE NRA,
THE NRA NOW SAYING THAT THEY ARE
NOT YET IN THE DEBATE.
THEY'LL COMMENT WITH HAD THEY
GET ALL THE INFORMATION FROM
THIS LATEST MASSACRE.
BUT WE'VE ALREADY HAD SOME
INDICATIONS, CONGRESSMAN MANCHIN
WHO SAYS, LOOK, PERHAPS I WILL
GO AHEAD AND SUGGEST TO MY NRA
FRIENDS THAT THEY NEED TO ENGAGE
AND NEED TO TAKE A DIFFERENT
APPROACH.
IS THIS THE MOMENT THAT THAT IS
EVEN POSSIBLE?
>> I HOPE SO BECAUSE WHAT I HOPE
THAT WE WILL DO IS NOW WE'LL
START LOOKING AT FACTS RATHER
THAN, YOU KNOW, EMOTIONS.
THE TIME FOR EMOTIONS REMAINS
WITH REGARD TO THIS HORRIFIC
TRAGEDY, BUT LET'S TRANSLATE
INTO ACTION.
AND THE ACTION DEPENDS ON FACTS.
WHY DO WE HAVE 15 TIMES AS MUCH
GUN HOMICIDE AS THE REST OF THE
WORLD?
WHAT CAN WE DO ABOUT IT?
WHAT CAN WE LEARN FROM OTHER
COUNTRIES THAT HAVE DEALT WITH
SOME OF THESE ISSUES?
WHY DO COUNTRIES LIKE JAPAN HAVE
THESE EXTRAORDINARILY LOW RATES
OF GUN HOME SKPOOICIDE AND GUN ?
IF WE CAN COME UP WITH SOMETHING
SENSIBLE -- AND FRANKLY, IF HAS
TO BE MORE FAR REACHING.
EVEN THE LEGISLATION PROPOSED BY
DIANNE FEINSTEIN, THOUGH A STEP
FORWARD, IT HAS 900 EXCEPTIONS
ON THE ASSAULT BAN.
900 SEPARATE EXCEPTIONS.
HOW CAN SOMETHING LIKE THAT BE
ENOUGH, GIVEN THE KIND OF
TRAGEDY WE'VE JUST SEEN?
>> AND FAREED, FINALLY, I WANT
TO READ THIS QUOTE FROM NEIL
McDONALD, A SENIOR WASHINGTON
CORRESPONDENT FOR CBC NEWS OFF
THE CANADA.
YET ANOTHER NATIONAL DISCUSSION
ABOUT GUNS IS UNDER WAY, AND
IT'S SO ANTI-RATIONAL, SO
POLITICALLY COWARDLY, SO
UNBEARABLY STUPID, THAT YOU HAVE
TO WONDER HOW A NATION THAT HAS
ENLIGHTENED THE WORLD IN SO MANY
OTHER WAYS COULD WALLOW IN THIS
KIND OF DISCUSSION.
DOES THIS TARGET THE UNITED
STATES' IMAGE IN THE EYES OF
MANY WHO LOOK AT THIS AND SAY,
REALLY?
ANOTHER GUN DISCUSSION?
>> OF COURSE IT DOES, AND IT
DOES FOR APPROPRIATE REASONS.
I'VE BEEN LISTENING TO SOME OF
THE COMMENTARY, AND YOU KNOW, WE
KEEP TALKING ABOUT THE EVIL OF
THIS PERSON AND THE PSYCHOLOGY
AND, YOU KNOW, MAYBE THE
VIOLENCE IN THE CULTURE.
ALL THAT COULD EXPLAIN ANY ONE
INSTANCE.
IT CANNOT EXPLAIN THE FACT THAT,
AS I SAY, WE HAVE 15 TIMES AS
MUCH GUN VIOLENCE AS OTHER
COUNTRIES.
WE HAVE TO BE WILLING TO
CONFRONT THE REALITY THAT WE'RE
WAY OUT OF LINE HERE, AND WE
HAVE SOMETHING TO LEARN FROM
OTHER PEOPLE.
>> ALL RIGHT.
GOT TO TAKE A REAL CRITICAL LOOK
AT OUR CULTURE HERE IN THE
UNITED STATES.
THANKS, FAREED.
REALLY APPRECIATE IT.
>> Reporter: FAITH TESTED BY
TRAGEDY.
WE'RE GOING TO HEAR FROM A
NEWTOWN SUNDAY SCHOOL TEACHER
ABOUT HOW SHE'S TALKING TO HER
STUDENTS ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED.
[ Male Announcer ]
RESEARCH SUGGESTS CELL HEALTH
PLAYS A KEY ROLE
THROUGHOUT OUR LIVES.
One A Day Men's 50+
IS A COMPLETE MULTIVITAMIN
DESIGNED FOR MEN'S HEALTH
CONCERNS AS WE AGE.
IT HAS 7 ANTIOXIDANTS
TO SUPPORT CELL HEALTH.
One A Day Men's 50+.
♪ BUT THE FIRE IS
SO DELIGHTFUL ♪
NOTHING MELTS AWAY THE COLD
LIKE A HOT, DELICIOUS BOWL
OF CHICKEN NOODLE SOUP
FROM CAMPBELL'S.
♪ LET IT SNOW, LET IT SNOW
>> Reporter: PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS
A MESSAGE FOR ALL OF US IN THE
AFTERMATH OF THE MASSACRE HERE
IN NEWTOWN.
THESE TRAGEDIES, HE SAYS, THEY
MUST END.
AT A PRAYER SERVICE LAST NIGHT,
THE PRESIDENT SAID HE WANTS THE
PEOPLE OF THIS HEARTBROKEN
COMMUNITY TO KNOW THEY ARE NOT
ALONE.
>> I COME TO OFFER THE LOVE AND
PRAYERS OF A NATION.
I AM VERY MINDFUL THAT MERE
WORDS CANNOT MATCH THE DEPTHS OF
YOUR SORROW, NOR CAN THEY HEAL
YOUR WOUNDED HEARTS.
I CAN ONLY HOPE IT HELPS FOR YOU
TO KNOW THAT YOU'RE NOT ALONE IN
YOUR GRIEF.
>> Reporter: THE PRESIDENT
TURNED TO SCRIPTURE AS A WAY TO
CONSOLE ALL THOSE SUFFERING
FAMILIES AND THE WHOLE
COMMUNITY.
MANY LOOK TO THEIR FAITH FOR
COMFORT AFTER A TRAGEDY LIKE
THIS.
EVEN SUNDAY SCHOOL KIDS.
AND HERE IN NEWTOWN, THERE WERE
SOME EMPTY SEATS IN ONE SUNDAY
SCHOOL CLASSROOM YESTERDAY.
JASON CARROLL HAS MORE.
>> Reporter: THIS IS WHERE SOME
OF THE CHILDREN WHO WERE KILLED
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY PRAYED
AND WENT TO SUNDAY SCHOOL AT
TRINITY EPISCOPAL CHURCH.
SUE VOGELMAN TAUGHT SOME OF
THOSE CHILDREN.
SHE WAS BACK ON THIS SUNDAY FOR
ALL HER STUDENTS INCLUDING SOME
OF THOSE WHO SURVIVED.
YOU HAD A LOT OF CHILDREN HERE
IN THIS ROOM.
WHAT WAS THAT LIKE FOR YOU?
>> IT WAS A LITTLE BIT -- IT WAS
ACTUALLY VERY SCARY BECAUSE I
SPENT YESTERDAY TRYING TO
PREPARE FOR TODAY, BUT YOU DON'T
KNOW WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN.
AND YOU KNOW, RIGHT IN THE
MIDDLE OF IT, A CHILD JUST
RAISED THEIR HAND.
I SAID YES.
AND THEY SAID, "MY FRIENDS
DIED."
AND THEN LATER ON WHEN WE GOT TO
THE PART WHERE WE PRAYED, PRETTY
MUCH EVERY CHILD IN HERE ALL HAD
A PRAYER.
AND MANY OF THEM WERE, "MY
FRIEND JACK DIED.
MY FRIEND BEN DIED.
MY FRIEND CHARLOTTE DIED."
SO WE PRAYED.
WE PRAYED -- WE PROBABLY PRAYED
MORE THAN WE'VE EVER PRAYED
BEFORE.
>> Reporter: VOGELMAN KNEW THERE
WOULD BE ANXIETY AMONG THE
CHILDREN AND THEIR PARENTS.
SHE SAW BOTH.
>> WE WERE A LITTLE WORRIED,
THERE WERE KIDS, THEIR PARENTS
HAD SAID THAT THEY DIDN'T WANT
TO COME TO CLASS BECAUSE, AGAIN,
IT'S LIKE A SCHOOL, AND THEY
WERE WORRIED.
AND THE FIRST GRADE CLASS, ONE
GIRL DIDN'T WANT TO COME BECAUSE
BEN WOULDN'T BE THERE.
SO THERE WAS A LOT OF ANXIETY.
BEN WOULD HAVE BEEN SITTING
RIGHT HERE ON THIS CARPET WITH
ME.
SO, YOU KNOW, WHEN THE KIDS
BRING IT UP THAT "MY FRIEND BEN
DIED," I HAD TO DO THE
TAEPDANCE.
WE HAVE ATTENDANCE SIGN-IN
PAGES.
AS I WAS PUTTING THEM IN THE
BOXES LAST NIGHT, THE FIRST
GRADE PAGE HAD BEN'S NAME ON IT.
AND I REMEMBER THINKING, THIS IS
GOING TO BE HANGING IN THE HALL,
AND HIS NAME'S NOT GOING TO BE
SIGNED IN.
I DIDN'T KNOW IF I SHOULD LEAVE
HIS NAME ON THERE OR TAKE IT
OFF.
SO I PRINTED ONE OUT WITH IT
AND AS I WAS GOING UP TO ASK
PASTOR KATHY, I STARTED CRYING.
IT REALLY HIT ME.
I DELETED HIS NAME.
>> Reporter: TO HELP EASE THE
GRIEF, VOGELMAN HAD THE CHILDREN
WRITE CARDS.
THIS ONE SAYS, "CHARLOTTE IS
SAFE NOW."
>> YEAH, THAT'S FOR CHARLOTTE.
THAT WAS FOR LITTLE CHARLOTTE
WHO WENT HERE.
>> Reporter: CHARLOTTE WAS 6
YEARS OLD.
ANOTHER CARD READS, IN PART,
"YOU'RE NOT ALONE."
VOGELMAN SAYS SHE FELT PRIDE,
STRENGTH SHE SAW IN THE
CHILDREN.
>> I'VE BEEN WORKING WITH KIDS
MY WHOLE ADULT LIFE.
THEY'RE MY KIDS.
YOU KNOW, PEOPLE ON FACEBOOK ARE
LIKE I'M SO GLAD YOUR KIDS ARE
OKAY.
I'M, LIKE, I AM OBVIOUSLY VERY
GLAD MY KIDS ARE OKAY, BUT MY
KIDS ARE NOT OKAY.
MY KIDS DIED.
THAT'S HOW EVERYONE FEELS IN
NEWTOWN.
SORRY.
THEY WERE BABIES.
>> Reporter: JASON CARROLL, CNN,
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> OF COURSE, THERE ARE NO EASY
ANSWERS AFTER A TRAGEDY LIKE
THIS.
BUT WHAT ARE LAWMAKERS,
POLITICIANS, CAN THEY EVEN DO
ANYTHING?
WE'LL GO LIVE TO WASHINGTON TO
FIND OUT.
I GAVE BIRTH TO MY DAUGHTER
ON MAY 18TH,
FIVE DAYS LATER,
I HAD A MASSIVE HEART ATTACK.
BAYER ASPIRIN WAS THE FIRST
THING THE EMTS GAVE ME.
NOW, I'M ON
A BAYER ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Male Announcer ] BE SURE
TO TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE YOU BEGIN
AN ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Woman ]
LEARN FROM MY STORY.
>>> MORE THAN 140,000 PEOPLE
HAVE SIGNED A PETITION URGING
THE OBAMA ADMINISTRATION TO
PROPOSE LIMITS ON GUN OWNERSHIP.
THIS IS THE PETITION.
IT'S POSTED ON THE WHITE HOUSE
WEBSITE'S WE THE PEOPLE SECTION.
AND IT READS "WHILE A NATIONAL
DIALOGUE IS CRITICAL, LAWS ARE
THE ONLY MEANS IN WHICH WE CAN
REDUCE THE NUMBER OF PEOPLE
MURDERED IN GUN-RELATED DEATHS.
POWERFUL LOBBYING GROUPS ALLOW
THE OWNERSHIP OF GUNS TO REACH
BEYOND THE CONSTITUTION'S
INTENDED PURPOSE OF THE RIGHT TO
BEAR ARMS."
WELL, THE WHITE HOUSE HAS TO
RESPOND TO PETITIONS THAT
RECEIVE MORE THAN 25,000
SIGNATURES.
SO SEVERAL DEMOCRATIC LAWMAKERS,
THEY ARE PROPOSING NEW
RESTRICTIONS ON GUNS IN THE
AFTERMATH OF THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING, THE MASSACRE IN
CONNECTICUT.
INDEPENDENT SENATOR JOE
LIEBERMAN, HE IS PROPOSING A
COMMISSION TO HOLD HEARINGS ON
THE ISSUE.
>> THIS IS ALL ABOUT TRYING TO
LIMIT ACCESS TO GUNS BY PEOPLE
WHO SHOULDN'T HAVE THEM BASED ON
THEIR RECORDS.
AND TO KEEP MILITARY WEAPONS OFF
OF THE COMMERCIAL MARKET.
THAT SHOULDN'T INHIBIT ANYBODY'S
RIGHT TO HUNT, TARGET SHOOT OR
EVEN DEFEND THEMSELVES WITH A
GUN.
>> I WANT TO BRING IN DANA BASH
FROM CAPITOL HILL.
AND DANA, YOU KNOW, A LOT OF
PEOPLE JUST GET REALLY
FRUSTRATED WHEN THEY HEAR
SOMETHING LIKE "ANOTHER
COMMISSION," "A STUDY"
"HEARINGS" ON THE ISSUE.
WHAT CAN LAWMAKERS DO?
>> Reporter: SUZANNE, AS SOON AS
THIS HAPPENED, I WENT BACK AND
LOOKED AT SOME OF THE STORIES I
DID ON THE QUESTION OF WHETHER
GUN CONTROL CAN HAPPEN AFTER
SOME OF THE SHOOTINGS THAT WE'VE
HAD OVER THE PAST SEVERAL YEARS.
UNFORTUNATELY, AS WE'VE BEEN
TALKING HERE, THEY'VE BEEN
HAPPENING ABOUT EVERY SIX
MONTHS.
THE MOVIE SHOOTING.
BEFORE THAT, THE ASSASSINATION
ATTEMPT OF FORMER CONGRESSWOMAN
GABBY GIFFORDS, AND THE ANSWER
ALWAYS WAS LIKELY NOTHING.
AND THE REASON WAS BECAUSE OF
DEMOCRATS.
DEMOCRATS HAVE POLITICALLY SHIED
AWAY FROM THIS ISSUE FROM THE
PAST DECADE OR SO JUST BECAUSE
IT'S BEEN BAD POLITICS FROM
THEM, AND THEY LEARNED THAT THE
HARD WAY, LOSING SEATS ON THE
CONGRESSIONAL LEVEL AND EVEN ON
THE PRESIDENTIAL LEVEL IN KEY
RED OR MORE RURAL STATES AND
DISTRICTS.
THIS TIME DOES SEEM TO BE
DIFFERENT BECAUSE THOSE
DEMOCRATS WHO SHIED AWAY ARE NOW
TALKING ABOUT IT.
CHUCK SCHUMER, FOR EXAMPLE, HE
SAID THAT HE COULD PUT THAT ON
THE TABLE AND MAYBE MOST
IMPORTANTLY JOE MANCHIN.
HE IS THE SENATOR FROM WEST
VIRGINIA, VERY PRO-GUN, USED
HIMSELF WITH A RIFLE IN SOME OF
HIS POLITICAL ADS.
HE SAYS IT'S TIME TO LOOK AT
THIS.
>> I JUST CAME WITH MY FAMILY
FROM DEER HUNTING.
I'VE NEVER HAD MORE THAN THREE
SHELLS IN A CLIP.
SOMETIMES YOU DON'T GET MORE
THAN ONE SHOT ANYWAY AT A DEER.
JUST COMMON SENSE.
IT'S TIME -- IT'S TIME TO MOVE
BEYOND RHETORIC.
WE NEED TO SIT DOWN AND HAVE A
COMMON-SENSE DISCUSSION AND MOVE
IN A REASONABLE WAY.
AND I ASK ALL MY FRIENDS IN THE
NRA MEMBER AND I'M A PROUD
MEMBER AND ALWAYS HAVE BEEN, WE
NEED TO SIT DOWN AND MOVE THIS
DIALOGUE TO A SENSIBLE,
REASONABLE APPROACH TO FIXING
PART OF IT, NOT ALL OF IT, BUT
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE ON THE
TABLE, AND I THINK IT WILL BE.
>> Reporter: NOW, DIANNE
FEINSTEIN, DEMOCRATIC SENATOR
FROM CALIFORNIA, HAS ALREADY
SAID SHE'S GOT AN ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN BILL WRITTEN THAT
SHE'LL PUT UP ON THE FIRST DAY
OF THE NEW CONGRESS.
OF COURSE, THE ASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN LAPSED IN 2004 WITH NOTHING
MORE THAN A SHOULDER SHRUG FROM
MOST PEOPLE UP HERE.
WHETHER OR NOT THAT CAN ACTUALLY
GET THE VOTES DESPITE THIS NEW
TALK IS ANOTHER QUESTION.
>> DANA, YOU BRING UP A REALLY
GOOD POINT BECAUSE YOU'RE
ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
I MEAN, PEOPLE HAVE JUST BEEN
SITTING ON THIS, NOTHING HAS
BEEN DONE FOR YEARS.
WE HEARD THE PRESIDENT COME OUT
VERY STRONGLY LAST NIGHT IN THAT
MEMORIAL AND BEFORE SAYING THAT,
YOU KNOW, WE HAVE TO DO
SOMETHING.
YOU CAN'T LET THIS JUST ACCEPT
THAT THIS IS THE WAY THIS IS IN
THE COUNTRY.
BUT WE ALSO KNOW THAT THE LAST
FOUR YEARS, THE PRESIDENT HAS
ACTUALLY EXPANDED GUN RIGHTS.
HE SIGNED LEGISLATION THAT WOULD
ALLOW FOLKS TO CARRY WEAPONS ON
AMTRAK TRAINS AND IN NATIONAL
PARKS, THOSE KINDS OF THINGS.
WHAT DO WE THINK HE IS SERIOUS
ABOUT DOING?
>> Reporter: YOU KNOW, THAT IS
REALLY THE BIG, OPEN QUESTION
BECAUSE EVERYBODY HERE ON
CAPITOL HILL FROM DEMOCRATS TO
REPUBLICANS, NO MATTER WHERE
THEY SIT ON THIS ISSUE, SAY THAT
IT IS IF SOMETHING IS DONE, IT'S
GOING TO HAVE TO COME FROM THE
BULLY PULPIT, FROM THE
PRESIDENT.
AND LISTENING TO HIM LAST NIGHT
ESPECIALLY, HE DEFINITELY DID
STRIKE A DIFFERENT TONE.
I MEAN, SUZANNE, YOU COVERED
HIM.
YOU SAW, HE CAMPAIGNED ON
REINSTATING THE ASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN IN 2008 BUT DIDN'T DO MUCH
ABOUT IT, DIDN'T DO ANYTHING
ABOUT IT, REALLY, BECAUSE AS I
SAID, DEMOCRATS HERE ON CAPITOL
HILL, MANY OF THEM JUST DIDN'T
WANT TO TOUCH IT.
THE OPEN QUESTION STILL IS THE
VOTES.
AND JUST EVEN LOOKING AHEAD,
YOU'VE GOT TO STILL TALK ABOUT
POLITICS.
THE NEXT ELECTION, 2014, YOU
HAVE A NUMBER OF DEMOCRATIC
SENATORS UP FOR RE-ELECTION IN
CONSERVATIVE STATES, WHETHER IT
IS KAY HAGAN OF NORTH CAROLINA
OR MARK BEGICH OF ALASKA OR MARK
PRIOR OF ARKANSAS.
THOSE ARE PEOPLE WHO WERE TRYING
TO GET IN TOUCH WITH THEIR
OFFICES BUT MAY BE RELUCTANT,
EVEN IN THE CASE OF THIS
HORRIBLE TRAGEDY, TO DO MUCH
BECAUSE THEY'RE AFRAID OF
GETTING PUMMELED BACK HOME.
THE ONE THING THAT MAYBE WE'RE
HEARING MORE TALK OF IS MAYBE
NOT SO FAR AS THE ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN, BUT SOMETHING TO
CURB THOSE 30-SHOT MAGAZINES,
THINGS LIKE THAT, WHICH EVEN JOE
MANCHIN SAYS, YOU DON'T NEED
THAT FOR ANYTHING, NOT EVEN
HUNTING.
>> THAT'S A VERY GOOD POINT.
WE KNOW THE JUSTICE DEPARTMENT
WAS LOOKING AT A NUMBER OF
THINGS AT LEAST TO BEEF UP THE
BACKGROUND PROCESS, THE
BACKGROUND CHECK PROCESS.
THEY DROPPED THAT DURING THE
CAMPAIGN, DURING THE RE-ELECTION
CAMPAIGN.
IT WILL BE VERY INTERESTING TO
SEE WHAT COMES OUT OF THE WHITE
HOUSE, WHAT THE PRESIDENT
DECIDES THAT HE IS GOING TO
STAND BEHIND AND REALLY PUSH
THROUGH CONGRESS.
DANA, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
REALLY APPRECIATE IT.
>>> THERE IS ANOTHER ISSUE, OF
COURSE, THAT THE PRESIDENT IS
DEALING WITH.
WE ARE ONLY 15 DAYS AWAY FROM
THIS FISCAL CLIFF.
SO THE PRESIDENT AND HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER MET AGAIN
TODAY AT THE WHITE HOUSE.
WHAT THEY'RE TRYING TO DO, WELL,
THEY'RE TRYING TO REACH THIS
DEFICIT REDUCTION DEAL BY
JANUARY 1st, TOP OF NEXT YEAR.
IF THEY DON'T DO IT, AUTOMATIC
SPENDING CUTS, THEY'RE GOING TO
GO INTO EFFECT.
PRACTICALLY EVERYONE'S TAXES ARE
GOING TO GO UP AS WELL.
WELL, A SOURCE IS TELLING CNN
THAT SPEAKER BOEHNER HAS NOW
AGREED, IN SOME FORM, TO RAISING
TAXES ON PEOPLE MAKING $1
MILLION A YEAR OR MORE.
THE WHITE HOUSE STILL WANTS A
TAX INCREASE ON HOUSEHOLDS THAT
ARE EARNING MORE THAN $250,000
OR MORE.
>>> SOUTH CAROLINA'S GOVERNOR
ANNOUNCED HER CHOICE TO REPLACE
REPUBLICAN SENATOR JIM DEMINT.
GOVERNOR NIKKI HALEY IS
APPOINTING GOP CONGRESSMAN TIM
SCOTT AS DEMINT'S SUCCESSOR.
NOW SCOTT WILL BECOME ONLY THE
SECOND AFRICAN-AMERICAN
REPUBLICAN SENATOR SINCE
RECONSTRUCTION.
DEMINT IS RESIGNING FROM THE
SENATE TO LEAD THE HERITAGE
FOUNDATION.
THAT, OF COURSE, A CONSERVATIVE
THINK TANK IN WASHINGTON.
HE MADE THAT ANNOUNCEMENT
EARLIER IN THE MONTH.
>>> AND WE WANT TO DO A CHECK ON
THE MARKETS.
YOU SEE THE DOW IS UP 83 POINTS
OR SO, SIGNS OF HOPE, PERHAPS,
THAT THE FISCAL CLIFF TALKS IN
WASHINGTON AND THE PROSPECT OF
AN ECONOMIC STIMULUS PLAN IN
JAPAN IS GOING TO HAVE INVESTORS
MORE OPTIMISTIC TODAY.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
When I'm trading,
I'm so into it,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
hours can go by before
I realize
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
that I haven't even
looked away from my screen.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
That kind of focus...
that's what I have
when I trade.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
And the StreetSmart Edge trading
platform from Charles Schwab...
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
...helps me keep an eye on
what's really important to me.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
It's packed with tools that
help me work my strategies,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
spot patterns and find
opportunities more easily.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Then, when I'm ready...
act decisively.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
I can even access it from the
cloud and trade on any computer.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
With the exact same tools,
the exact same way.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
And the reality is,
with Schwab Mobile,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
I can focus on trading
anyplace, anytime...
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
...until I choose to focus
on something else.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Trade at Schwab for
$8.95 a trade.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Open an account and trade
up to 6 months commission-free
online equity trading
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
with a $50,000 deposit.
Call 1-800-786-7803
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
and a Trading Specialist
will help you get started today.
>>> IN THE HOURS AFTER THE
RAMPAGE IN NEWTOWN, THE MOTHER
OF A 13-YEAR-OLD BOY IN IDAHO,
SHE WROTE AN ESSAY.
IT IS STARTLING ABOUT HER OWN
LIFE.
IT'S GETTING A LOT OF ATTENTION
ONLINE.
MOST OF THE TIME SHE'S A SWEET
KID WHO LOVES HARRY POTTER AND
STUFFED ANIMALS, BUT THEN THIS
QUOTE.
THIS IS FROM THE MOTHER.
A FEW WEEKS AGO, MICHAEL PULLED
A KNIFE AND THREATENED TO KILL
ME AND THEN HIMSELF AFTER I
ASKED HIM TO RETURN HIS OVERDUE
LIBRARY BOOKS.
THAT CONFLICT ENDED WITH THREE
BURLY POLICE OFFICERS AND A
PARAMEDIC WRESTLING MY SON TO A
GURNEY AND AN EXPENSIVE
AMBULANCE RIDE TO THE LOCAL
EMERGENCY ROOM.
LIZA SAYS HER SON'S I.Q. IS OFF
THE CHARTS BUT THAT HE COULD
SNAP AT ANY TIME.
ANTI-PSYCHOTIC, MOOD-ALTERING
DRUGS HAVE NOT HELPED BECAUSE
SHE SAYS SHE THINKS THAT THERE
IS THE POTENTIAL HERE OF THIS
CHILLING THOUGHT THAT THIS COULD
HAPPEN.
>> EVERY TIME I HEAR ABOUT A
MASS SHOOTING, I THINK ABOUT MY
SON.
AND I WONDER IF SOMEDAY I'LL BE
THAT MOM.
>> I AM JOINED BY JEFF GRENIER,
LICENSED CLINICAL PSYCHOLOGIST.
SHE THINKS THAT HER OWN CHILD IN
SOME WAY COULD COMMIT THE KIND
OF CRIME THAT WE SAW FROM THIS
YOUNG MAN, ADAM LANZA, LAST
WEEK.
WHAT KIND OF HELP IS THERE FOR
HER AND FOR OTHER PARENTS WHO
ARE AFRAID IN SOME WAYS OF THEIR
MENTALLY ILL CHILDREN?
>> WELL, IT'S A VERY TOUGH
TERRAIN, SUZANNE, FOR MANY OF
THESE PARENTS.
I WORK WITH THEM EVERY SINGLE
DAY.
THEY HAVE CHILDREN WHO ARE ON
THE ONSET OF SCHIZOPHRENIA OR A
VERY SERIOUS PERSONALITY
DISORDER SUCH AS A SCHIZO TYPE
WHERE WE DON'T HAVE THE
HALLUCINATIONS BUT WE DO HAVE
THE MAGICAL THINKING AND
ISOLATION AND SOMETIMES SOME
NAKED AGGRESSION.
AND WHAT HAPPENS IS BECAUSE AT
THE TIME THEY MAY NOT BE A
DANGER TO THEMSELVES OR OTHERS,
YOU CAN'T GET THEM INVOLUNTARILY
COMMITTED, ESPECIALLY IF THEY
ARE OF AGE.
AND IF YOU ARE ABLE TO GET THEM
INTO THE EMERGENCY ROOM AND
ADMITTED BY A PSYCHIATRIST
BECAUSE THERE ISN'T A LOT OF BED
SPACE, WITHIN TWO OR THREE DAYS,
THEY ARE DISCHARGED, ON
MEDICATIONS, BUT THE MEDICATIONS
HAVE SUCH SEVERE SIDE EFFECTS
THAT EVEN OLDER ADULTS BUT IN
THIS CASE YOUNGER ADULTS DON'T
WANT TO TAKE THAT MEDICATION,
AND THAT'S THE CONUNDRUM.
>> AND SHE WRITES HERE, SHE GOES
ON TO SAY, I DON'T BELIEVE MY
SON BELONGS IN JAIL, BUT IT
SEEMS LIKE THE UNITED STATES IS
USING PRISON AS THE SOLUTION OF
CHOICE FOR MENTALLY ILL PEOPLE.
WHAT KINDS OF OPTIONS DOES SHE
HAVE?
>> WELL, SHE CERTAINLY IS
SPEAKING OUT OF FRUSTRATION.
WE DON'T WANT TO USE JAILS IN
THAT WAY.
I WAS A CHIEF PSYCHOLOGIST FOR
FEDERAL PRISON FOR MANY YEARS,
BUT I CAN TELL YOU, BECAUSE A
LOT OF THESE FOLKS COULDN'T GET
INTO PSYCHIATRIC HOSPITALS,
SOMETIMES THE MARSHALS, THE
POLICE OFFICERS, WOULD BRING
THEM TO JAIL BECAUSE THEY WERE
SO DANGEROUS THAT YOU COULDN'T
KEEP THEM ON THE STREETS, BUT
YET IT WAS CRAZY, NO PUN
INTENDED, BUT WE COULDN'T KEEP
THEM IN THE HOSPITALS.
BUT WHAT WE REALLY WANT TO DO AT
THIS POINT IS TO DIAGNOSE AS
EARLY AS POSSIBLE, MAKE SURE
THAT WE TRY TO KEEP THE KIDS ON
THESE MEDICATIONS.
THERE ARE 15 DIFFERENT
ANTI-PSYCHOTIC MEDICATIONS AND
MORE BEING MADE, SO YOU DO HAVE
TO FIND THE RIGHT MEDICATION.
YOU HAVE TO MANAGE THE SIDE
EFFECTS, BUT YOU HAVE TO KEEP
THEM IN THERAPY.
AND PARENTS JUST HAVE TO TRY TO
BE CONSISTENT IN MAKING SURE
THAT THEIR KIDS GET HELP.
>> AND JEFF, IT CERTAINLY SEEMS
LIKE YOU'VE GOT TO DEAL WITH THE
STIGMA.
SOME PEOPLE STILL FEEL LIKE YOU
CAN TREAT ANY OTHER ILLNESS, BUT
IF IT'S A MENTAL ILLNESS, THEY
DON'T TALK ABOUT IT.
PEOPLE TREAT THEM BADLY.
YOU REALLY HAVE TO DEAL WITH
THAT AS A SOCIETY AND AS A
CULTURE AS WELL.
JEFF, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
REALLY APPRECIATE YOUR
PERSPECTIVE.
OUR SPECIAL COVERAGE OF THE
CONNECTICUT SHOOTING CONTINUING
AFTER A QUICK BREAK.
>> Reporter: HERE'S LIEUTENANT
PAUL VANCE OF THE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE.
HE'S BRIEFING REPORTERS, ALL OF
US, ON THE INVESTIGATION.
>> -- LITERALLY THE WORD IS
"PLEAD."
FAMILIES ARE GRIEVING.
MANY OF THE FAMILIES HAVE ASKED
TO PLEASE AFFORD THEM THEIR
PRIVACY AS THEY GO THROUGH THIS
TER SHS T
TERRIBLE TRAGEDY.
THE LIEUTENANT HAS ASKED ME TO
PASS THAT ON TO YOU AS CONCISELY
AS POSSIBLE.
THAT'S THE BEST WAY I CAN DO IT.
AT THIS TIME I CAN TAKE A COUPLE
QUESTIONS.
WE'LL SEE IF WE CAN CLEAR UP
ANYTHING.
THEN I'M GOING TO SPEAK A LITTLE
BIT ABOUT OUR FUTURE
GET-TOGETHERS.
>> [ INAUDIBLE ].
>> CORRECT.
>> YOU'RE GOING TO ASK ME A HARD
QUESTION, AND I'M TRYING TO
RECALL.
THERE WERE TWO PHONE CALLS.
THE QUESTION WAS ABOUT THE
THREATS.
THERE WERE TWO THREATS OF
VIOLENCE.
WE CAN JUST SIMPLY SAY THAT CAME
IN, TWO SEPARATE PHONE CALLS
AGAINST THE SAME FACILITY, WHICH
WAS THE CHURCH, THE CATHOLIC
CHURCH IN TOWN.
TWO TELEPHONE CALLS RECEIVED.
AGAIN, AS I STATED BEFORE, THOSE
ARE CRIMINAL ACTS.
THOSE ARE ACTS THAT ARE BEING
THOROUGHLY AND COMPLETELY
INVESTIGATED, AND FOLLOW-UP WILL
BE DONE BY EITHER STATE OR
FEDERAL AUTHORITIES RELATIVE TO
ANY THREATS OF THAT NATURE THAT
SOMEONE SET FORTH.
THOSE WERE THE TWO THREATS.
NEXT, PLEASE.
>> [ INAUDIBLE ] ANY INDICATION
WHERE AND HOW LONG?
>> CERTAINLY -- YOU KNOW, AND I
CAN'T EVEN BEGIN TO SPECULATE.
WE JUST SIMPLY DON'T HAVE THAT
INFORMATION TO PROVIDE TO YOU.
AS I'VE STATED NUMEROUS TIMES,
WE DEFINITELY -- WE DEFINITELY
ARE PEELING THAT ONION BACK
LAYER BY LAYER, AND WE'LL KNOW
ALL THAT INFORMATION.
AND BELIEVE ME WHEN I TELL YOU,
THERE'S A TEAM THAT ARE WORKING
ON JUST THAT, WORKING WITH ATF
AND FEDERAL -- OTHER FEDERAL
AUTHORITIES, STATE AUTHORITIES
AND LOCAL AUTHORITIES TO MAKE
SURE THAT NO STONE IS LEFT
UNTURNED REGARDING THAT SPECIFIC
TRAINING, SIR.
YES, SIR.
>> DID HE REMOVE THE HARD DRIVE
AT HIS HOME [ INAUDIBLE ] THAT'S
MAKING IT DIFFICULT
[ INAUDIBLE ].
>> I DIDN'T INDICATE WHAT
EVIDENCE THAT'S BEEN SEIZED AT
ANY LOCATION.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE THAT
INFORMATION CAME FROM.
BUT WE DID SEIZE SIGNIFICANT
EVIDENCE AT THE RESIDENCE.
WE ARE ANALYZING AND WILL
ANALYZE, AND THAT'S A VERY
PAINSTAKING PROCESS IN FORENSIC
SCIENCE.
IT'S GOING TO TAKE SOME TIME TO
DO THAT.
WE DON'T DISCUSS EVIDENCE, SIR,
I'M SORRY.
WE DO NOT DISCUSS EVIDENCE, ITS
CONTENT OR DETAIL WHAT IT IS.
YES, SIR.
>> CAN YOU CLARIFY JUST A COUPLE
OF THINGS.
>> YES, SIR.
>> YOU SAID EARLIER THERE WERE
TWO PEOPLE WHO WERE SHOT AND
SURVIVED.
>> THAT'S CORRECT, SIR.
>> DO YOU KNOW WHERE -- WHAT
LOCATION OF THE SCHOOL?
>> I CAN'T.
THE QUESTION WAS, THERE WERE TWO
PEOPLE THAT WERE WOUNDED IN THIS
AND DID SURVIVE, TWO ADULTS,
THAT IS CORRECT.
THERE WERE WOUNDED IN THE LOWER
EXTREMITIES.
I DO NOT KNOW THE LOCATION IN
THE SCHOOL.
I CANNOT ANSWER THAT QUESTION.
>> DO YOU KNOW HOW MANY STUDENTS
WERE IN EACH CLASSROOM, HOW MANY
SURVIVORS WERE IN EACH
CLASSROOM?
>> NO.
>> VERSUS HOW MANY --
>> NO, I'M SORRY, I DON'T.
HE'S ASKING ABOUT, DO WE HAVE
SPECIFIC LOCATION OF SURVIVORS
AND LOCATION OF STUDENTS AND
FACULTY AND STAFF, AND I DON'T
HAVE THAT, I'M SORRY.
YES, MA'AM.
>> HAVE YOU IDENTIFIED ANY OF
THE INJURED ADULTS YET?
>> NO, WE HAVE NOT.
THEY'RE CONSIDERED WITNESSES,
AND WE DO NOT IDENTIFY
WITNESSES.
YES, MA'AM.
>> IN THE CASE OF THE ELECTRONIC
EVIDENCE WAS DESTROYED OR
UNAVAILABLE, WILL YOU BE WORKING
WITH INTERNET COMPANIES LIKE
GOOGLE AND TWITTER, FACEBOOK AND
OTHERS TO GET INFORMATION?
>> GOOD QUESTION AND GOOD WAY TO
ASK IT, BUT I CAN ONLY TELL YOU
WE'VE SEIZED EVIDENCE IF -- IF
THERE IS COMPUTER EVIDENCE.
AND I STRENUOUSLY SAY THAT, IF.
WE DO HAVE A COMPUTER TEAM, AND
OUR STATE AND FERENTZ ORENSICS
LABORATORY THAT ARE RETRIEVING
ANY TYPE OF EVIDENCE AND DATA.
I'LL LEAVE THAT THERE, PLEASE.
>> IS THERE ANY UPDATE ON THE
SCHOOLS THAT WERE LOCKED DOWN
EARLIER TODAY?
>> NO, THOSE WILL BE HANDLED BY
LOCAL AUTHORITIES.
THOSE TWO LOCKDOWNS IN
SURROUNDING COMMUNITIES HAVE
BEEN CLEARED, YES.
>> CAN YOU TELL US IF THE
ALLEGED BUSHMASTER ASSAULT RIFLE
IS LEGAL UNDER CONNECTICUT'S LAW
TO POSSESS BY ANYONE?
>> I CANNOT TELL YOU THAT
BECAUSE I DO NOT KNOW.
AS I SAID THIS MORNING, THAT
WEAPON, FROM THE DAY IT WAS
BUILT TO THE DAY WE SEIZED IT,
WE WILL LOOK AT EVERY ASPECT OF
IT FROM STEM TO STERN, WHERE
IT'S BEEN, WHO'S HAD IT AND ALL
THE CLIPS, THE AMMUNITION,
EVERYTHING TO DO WITH ALL THE
WEAPONS.
>> JUST A FOLLOW-UP TO THAT, A
LOT OF PEOPLE WATCHING AT HOME
SAY THERE'S NO MYSTERY HERE
ANYMORE.
BUT THERE'S SO MUCH EFFORT BEING
PUT INTO THE INVESTIGATION.
AND THEY MIGHT SAY THERE WILL
NEVER BE JUSTICE.
WHAT ARE THE ANSWERS THAT YOU'RE
GETTING?
>> THE ANSWERS ARE FOR THE POOR
VICTIMS, THE FAMILIES, THE
PEOPLE OF CONNECTICUT THAT NEED
TO KNOW AND SEE A CLEAR PICTURE
AS TO EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED
HERE.
AS I SAID MANY TIMES, THERE ARE
MANY PEOPLE, INCLUDING FIRST
RESPONDERS, INCLUDING TOWN
RESIDENTS, INCLUDING PEOPLE
RIGHT IN THIS AUDIENCE THAT HAVE
BROKEN HEARTS OVER THIS.
AND WE'RE GOING TO DO EVERYTHING
THAT IT TAKES TO ENSURE THAT WE
UNCOVER EVERY BIT OF EVIDENCE,
THAT WE ARE EXPECTING EVERY
FACET OF IT, THAT WE CONDUCT AS
MANY INTERVIEWS WITH EVERYONE
THAT WE NEED TO DO TO PAINT A
CLEAR PICTURE AS TO EXACTLY HOW
AND WHY THIS TRAGEDY OCCURRED.
YES, MA'AM.
>> CAN YOU CLARIFY THE MOTHER,
THE .22 CALIBER RIFLE AND WERE
OTHER GUNS SEIZED IN HOUSE?
>> I CAN'T ANSWER THAT, AGAIN,
MA'AM, ANYTHING THAT WAS SEIZED
IN THAT HOUSE WOULD BE EVIDENCE.
AND AS FAR AS THE WOUNDS THAT
THE VICTIM SUFFERED, THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER WAS VERY CLEAR, IT WAS
MULTIPLE GUNSHOT WOUNDS, AND
THAT'S AS FAR AS WE WENT WITH
THAT DESCRIPTION, MA'AM.
ONE MORE QUESTION.
YES, SIR.
>> CAN YOU SPEAK ANY -- CAN YOU
SPEAK ANY MORE TO THE CONNECTION
BETWEEN THE SHOOTER?
>> THERE WAS NO CONNECTION
BETWEEN THE SHOOTER AND THE
SCHOOL ACCORDING TO SCHOOL
AUTHORITIES HERE IN NEWTOWN.
>> NOT AT ALL.
>> ACCORDING TO SCHOOL
AUTHORITIES IN NEWTOWN.
>> CAN YOU ANSWER ABOUT A
LOCKDOWN IN A SCHOOL NEARBY
TODAY?
>> WE ADDRESSED THAT BEFORE AND
I'LL RESTATE THAT.
THERE WAS -- IN ANYTHING
WHATSOEVER TO DO WITH SCHOOL
SECURITY, ANYWHERE WITHIN OUR
STATE, WE'RE OBVIOUSLY ALL ON
THE EDGE, ARE ALL ON EDGE IN
ANYTHING THAT'S SUSPICIOUS,
ANYTHING THAT EVEN REMOTELY
APPEARS TO BE A LACK OF SECURITY
OR A BREACH OF SECURITY, ANY
EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTION IN
CONNECTICUT, AND I'M SURE IN
SURROUNDING STATES AND ACROSS
THE COUNTRY WILL TREAT IT VERY,
VERY SERIOUS.
THIS MORNING THERE WAS A
SUSPICIOUS INDIVIDUAL IN CLOSE
PROXIMITY TO ONE OF THE SCHOOLS.
A LOCAL POLICE DEPARTMENT
RESPONDED, INVESTIGATED AND
CLEARED THE MATTER.
IT WAS NOT A THREAT, BUT IN
DOING SO, THEY DID PUT NEARBY
SCHOOLS IN LOCKDOWN SIMPLY AS A
PRECAUTION.
I DO KNOW THAT ACROSS THE STATE,
THE GOVERNOR AND THE EDUCATION
COMMISSIONER AND LOCAL
AUTHORITIES AND LOCAL OFFICIALS
ARE PUTTING A LITTLE BIT OF
EXTRA SECURITY.
WE'RE SUPPORTING THE EDUCATIONAL
SYSTEM THROUGHOUT THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE CERTAINLY, AS YOU WELL
KNOW, THE TEACHERS ARE WELL
TRAINED.
THE FACULTY ARE WELL TRAINED.
ALL THE PERSONNEL IN THE SCHOOL
ARE WELL TRAINED.
THEY PRACTICE FOR FIRE DRILLS,
FOR EMERGENCIES.
AND BELIEVE ME, THE BLANKET OF
SECURITY ON PUBLIC SAFETY IS
GOING TO BE STRICT IN THE STATE
OF CONNECTICUT.
WHAT I'D LIKE TO TELL YOU TODAY,
THIS IS GOING TO BE OUR LAST
PRESS GATHERING TODAY.
WE'VE COME TO A POINT IN THIS
INVESTIGATION, YES, WE ARE STILL
WORKING, BUT I DON'T WANT TO
KEEP YOU HERE, AND I DON'T WANT
TO KEEP COMING UP AND TRYING TO
GIVE YOU INFORMATION IF WE HAVE
NO NEW INFORMATION TO GIVE YOU.
WHAT WE'RE GOING TO DO IS I
HANDED OUT A SLIP THAT GIVES YOU
INFORMATION.
ANYTHING NEW IS GOING TO BE
POSTED ON OUR WEBSITE.
ALL PRESS RELEASES, ALL PRESS
ANNOUNCEMENTS WILL BE POSTED ON
OUR WEBSITE.
IF THERE WERE ANYTHING THAT
ERUPTED OR EVOLVED DURING THIS
INVESTIGATION AND WE NEEDED TO
HOLD A PRESS CONFERENCE, IT
WOULD HAVE TO BE SOMETHING
SIGNIFICANT, THEN WE'D GIVE YOU
AMPLE TIME TO GATHER AT A
CENTRAL LOCATION AND PROVIDE
THAT BETWEEN THE LIEUTENANT FROM
NEWTOWN AND MYSELF.
I, AGAIN, AM IMPLORING YOU TO
PLEASE GIVE THE FAMILIES PRIVACY
AS THEY GO THROUGH THIS VERY
DEVASTATING PERIOD OF TIME IN
THEIR LIFE.
WE WILL STAY IN CONTACT.
IF YOU HAVE SPECIFIC QUESTIONS,
WE CAN ADDRESS THEM VIA E-MAIL.
THAT WOULD BE THE SMARTEST AND
THE BEST WAY.
AND WE'LL BE MORE THAN HAPPY TO
ADDRESS THAT.
YES, SIR.
>> I'M WONDERING, OBVIOUSLY,
MOTIVE IS THE KEY QUESTION WE
ASK YOU ALL THE TIME.
>> YES, SIR.
>> YOU KEEP DEFERRING IT.
CAN YOU GIVE PEOPLE SOME
GUIDANCE, PEOPLE WHO MIGHT BE
IMPATIENT ABOUT HOW LONG IT
MIGHT TAKE, WHY IT TAKES SO LONG
AND HOW LONG MIGHT WE HAVE TO
WAIT BEFORE YOU COME UP WITH A
MOTIVE TO TELL US?
JUST SO WE HAVE SOME IDEA.
>> THAT'S A LONG QUESTION, AND
THE ANSWER IS VERY LONG, BUT I
CAN SIMPLY TELL YOU, AS WE'VE
BEEN ALLUDING TO BETWEEN
NEWTOWN, STATE POLICE, OTHER LAW
ENFORCEMENT AGENCIES, FEDERAL
AUTHORITIES, ANALYSIS OF
EVIDENCE, CONDUCTING HUNDREDS OF
INTERVIEWS, LITERALLY HUNDREDS
OF INTERVIEWS, PUTTING THAT
WHOLE PACKAGE TOGETHER AND
FOLLOWING EACH PIECE OF EVIDENCE
ON EVERY TRAIL THAT IT GOES,
IT'S GOING TO TAKE A SUBSTANTIAL
AMOUNT OF TIME.
I KNOW -- WE KNOW AS
INVESTIGATORS THAT THE PEOPLE OF
CONNECTICUT, THE PEOPLE OF THIS
TOWN OF NEWTOWN WANT TO KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED.
WE'RE GOING TO DO THAT.
WE'RE GOING TO PROVIDE THEM ANY
INFORMATION AND ALL INFORMATION.
WE'LL PAINT A CRYSTAL-CLEAR
PICTURE AS MUCH AS WE POSSIBLY
CAN.
BUT IT IS A SLOW PROCESS.
IT'S NOT SOMETHING THAT JUST IS
DONE IN 60 MINUTES, AS YOU SEE
ON TV.
WE WILL KEEP THE PUBLIC
INFORMED.
WE WILL MAKE SURE IF THERE'S
ANYTHING THAT'S EMERGENT, THAT
WE GET IT OUT IMMEDIATELY AND
THAT IT'S THROUGH YOU FOLKS.
I WANT TO THANK YOU FOR
EVERYTHING THAT YOU'VE DONE.
YOU FOLKS HAVE BEEN VERY
PROFESSIONAL, AND WE DO
DEFINITELY APPRECIATE THAT, ALL
RIGHT?
THANK YOU.
>> CAN YOU CONFIRM THAT HE MAY
HAVE BEEN WEARING A BULLETPROOF
VEST?
>> NO, I CANNOT.
>> Reporter: HE'S BEEN BRIEFING
US SOMETIMES TWO, THREE, FOUR
TIMES A DAY, ALTHOUGH HE SAYS
THIS WILL BE HIS LAST FORMAL
BRIEFING OF THE DAY.
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE, THE
SPOKESMAN FOR THE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE TELLING US THAT
YES, THERE ARE DEVELOPMENTS, BUT
HE'S RELUCTANT TO PROVIDE TOO
MANY DETAILS RIGHT NOW OUT OF
RESPECT TO THOSE WHO HAVE
SUFFERED SO MUCH.
WE'LL TAKE A QUICK BREAK.
MUCH MORE RIGHT AFTER THIS.
PEOPLE HAVE DOUBTS
ABOUT TAKING ASPIRIN FOR PAIN.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
♪ OOH BABY,
CAN I DO FOR YOU TODAY? ♪
[ Female Announcer ] NEED HELP
KEEPING YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE?
ALIGN CAN HELP.
ONLY ALIGN HAS BIFANTIS,
A PATENTED PROBIOTIC
THAT NATURALLY HELPS MAINTAIN
YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE.
TRY ALIGN TO HELP RETAIN
A BALANCED DIGESTIVE SYSTEM.
TRY THE #1 GASTROENTEROLOGIST
RECOMMENDED PROBIOTIC.
ALIGN.
>>> WELL, FIRST THE UNTHINKABLE
HAPPENED.
TODAY NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
FACES WHAT SEEMS TO BE THE
UNBEARABLE.
FUNERALS FOR TWO OF THE
6-YEAR-OLDS KILLED IN THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL MASSACRE.
THEY ARE BEING HELD AT THIS
HOUR.
I'M SUZANNE MALVEAUX IN ATLANTA
WITH "NEWSROOM'S" SPECIAL
COVERAGE AS NEWTOWN REMEMBERS.
>> Reporter: AND I'M WOLF
BLITZER HERE IN NEWTOWN.
THE FUNERALS WILL GO ON FOR DAYS
AS 20 CHILDREN AND THE 6 ADULTS
WHO TRIED TO PROTECT THEM ARE
LAID TO REST.
ALL OF THIS FOLLOWING A MOVING
AND EMOTIONAL SERVICE LAST
NIGHT.
♪
IT INCLUDED A PRAYER SUNG BY A
RABBI, READINGS FROM THE BIBLE
AND THE KORAN, PRAYERS FROM
CHRISTIAN LEADERS AND A PROMISE
FROM PRESIDENT OBAMA.
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS, I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT, TO MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS, TO PARENTS
AND EDUCATORS IN AN EFFORT AIMED
AT PREVENTING MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS.
>> ALSO LAST NIGHT, THE CROWD AT
THE PRAYER SERVICE GAVE A
STANDING OVATION TO THE FIRST
RESPONDERS WHO ANSWERED THE CALL
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
I WANT TO UPDATE YOU ON THE
INVESTIGATION AND IN THE
AFTERMATH OF THAT MASSACRE.
HERE IS WHAT WE KNOW.
POLICE SAY TWO PEOPLE SHOT AND
WOUNDED IN THE RAMPAGE ARE
ACTUALLY RECOVERING.
INITIAL REPORTS INDICATED ONLY
ONE PERSON WHO WAS WOUNDED HAD
SURVIVED.
INVESTIGATORS CONTINUE PIECING
TOGETHER EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED.
THEY SAY THEY'RE NOT GOING TO
STOP UNTIL THEY HAVE INTERVIEWED
EVERY WITNESS, ANALYZE EVERY
PIECE OF EVIDENCE INCLUDING EACH
ROUND OF AMMUNITION.
FACULTY MEMBERS, THEY ARE
MEETING TODAY.
AND SCHOOLS IN NEWTOWN WILL
REOPEN TOMORROW.
BUT CLASSES AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY WILL BE SUSPENDED
UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE.
>>> WELL, THEY WERE FIRST GRADE
CLASSMATES.
FUNERAL SERVICES ARE BEING HELD
THIS HOUR FOR JACK PINTO AND
NOAH POZNER.
BRIGHT-EYED LITTLE BOYS WHOSE
LIVES WERE CUT SHORT BY THE
MASSACRE.
THEY WERE TWO OF THE 20 CHILDREN
WHO DIED IN THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL SHOOTING ON FRIDAY.
SANDRA ENDO JOINS US FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
SANDRA, I CAN'T EVEN IMAGINE
WHAT THE FAMILIES AND THE
COMMUNITY ARE GOING THROUGH AT
THIS POINT.
TELL US WHAT WE ARE LEARNING
ABOUT THESE TWO LITTLE BOYS.
>> Reporter: WELL, LITTLE JACK
PINTO, SUZANNE, WAS A BIG SPORTS
FAN.
HE LOVED BASEBALL, BASKETBALL
AND WRESTLING.
HE EVEN WON HIS FIRST WRESTLING
MATCH AND WON A MEDAL.
AND WE'RE TOLD THAT SOME OF HIS
TEAMMATES CAME TO HIS FUNERAL
WEARING MEDALS AS WELL.
BUT HIS FAVORITE SPORT WAS
FOOTBALL.
AND HIS IDOL WAS NEW YORK
GIANTS' RECEIVER VICTOR CRUZ.
AND OVER THE WEEKEND DURING THE
GAME, VICTOR CRUZ WORE A TRIBUTE
TO PINTO ON HIS GLOVE SAYING
"TODAY'S GAME IS FOR YOU, JACK."
HERE'S ALSO WHAT HE HAD TO SAY.
>> IT WAS VERY EMOTIONAL.
OBVIOUSLY GOING IN WHEN A FAMILY
IS FACING THAT MUCH TRAGEDY, YOU
WANT TO BE SOMEONE THAT INSPIRES
THEM, SOMEONE THAT CAN PUT A
SMILE ON THEIR FACE IN A TIME
WHEN IT'S TOUGH TO DO THAT.
IT WAS DEFINITELY AN EMOTIONAL
ONE GOING IN, AND WE WANTED THIS
VICTORY.
>> Reporter: OF COURSE, A VERY,
VERY EMOTIONAL AND SAD DAY HERE
IN NEWTOWN.
JACK PINTO, ONLY 6 YEARS OLD.
SUZANNE?
>> TELL US ABOUT HIS CLASSMATE,
NOAH.
>> Reporter: WELL, NOAH, HE IS
ALSO 6 YEARS OLD.
HE JUST TURNED 6 A MONTH AGO.
AND HE WILL ALSO BE LAID TO REST
HERE IN NEWTOWN.
HERE'S WHAT HIS AUNT HAD TO SAY,
TALKING WITH CNN FROM SEATTLE.
>> NOAH WAS EXTREMELY LIVELY.
HE WAS REALLY THE LIGHT OF THE
ROOM.
HE HAD A HUGE HEART.
AND HE WAS SO MUCH FUN.
A LITTLE BIT RAMBUNCTIOUS, LOTS
OF SPIRIT.
HE LOVED PLAYING WITH ALL OF HIS
COUSINS.
HE LOVED HIS TWIN THE MOST OF
ALL AND ALWAYS SAID THAT THEY
WERE BEST FRIENDS.
HE JUST -- YOU KNOW, THOSE BIG
BLUE EYES.
HE WAS A GORGEOUS, GORGEOUS BOY.
AND HE COULD REALLY GET WHAT HE
WANTED JUST BY BATTING THOSE
LONG EYELASHES AND LOOKING AT
YOU WITH THOSE BIG BLUE EYES.
YOU REALLY COULDN'T SAY NO TO
HIM.
>> Reporter: LIVES CERTAINLY
TAKEN TOO SOON.
AND ACCORDING TO FAMILY MEMBERS
OF NOAH, HE LOVED HIS LITTLE
SISTER, HIS TWIN SISTER,
SURVIVES HIM, AND FAMILY MEMBERS
SAY THEY STILL DON'T KNOW HOW TO
EXPLAIN TO HER HOW EXACTLY HE
PASSED AWAY.
SUZANNE.
>> I UNDERSTAND HIS TWIN SISTER
WAS IN ANOTHER CLASSROOM, IS
THAT RIGHT, THAT THEY WERE NOT
IN THE SAME CLASS TOGETHER
BECAUSE THEY SEPARATE TWINS.
THEY DON'T ACTUALLY ALLOW THEM
TO BE IN THE SAME CLASS.
>> Reporter: THAT'S RIGHT.
SHE DID SURVIVE THE HORRIFIC
SHOOTING.
AND OF COURSE, THAT'S SOMETHING
A LOT OF THESE STUDENTS HERE AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY WILL HAVE
TO DEAL WITH.
THEY ARE STILL GRAPPLING WITH
FIGURING OUT WHERE TO RESUME
CLASSES HERE IN NEWTOWN.
TODAY ALL SCHOOLS ARE SUSPENDED.
TOMORROW MOST CLASSES WILL
RESUME.
BUT OF COURSE FOR THE STUDENTS
AT SANDY HOOK, THEY WILL STILL
HAVE SUSPENDED CLASSES UNTIL
THEY CAN FIND ANOTHER LOCATION.
>> ALL RIGHT.
SANDRA, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
IT'S SUCH A LOSS.
WOLF?
>> Reporter: IT'S A TRAGEDY
BEYOND BELIEF OR UNDERSTANDING.
PEOPLE WANT TO KNOW WHAT COULD
HAVE DRIVEN A YOUNG MAN TO KILL
HIS OWN MOTHER AND THEN GUN DOWN
20 YOUNG CHILDREN AND 6 ADULTS?
INEVITABLY, QUESTIONS ARE BEING
RAISED ABOUT HIS CHILDHOOD AND
HIS FAMILY LIFE.
OUR OWN DEBORAH FEYERICK IS HERE
IN NEWTOWN.
SHE'S GOT MORE ON WHAT'S GOING
ON.
PART OF THIS INVESTIGATION.
WHAT ARE WE HEARING ABOUT, FOR
EXAMPLE, THE COMPUTERS FOUND
INSIDE THE HOME OF THE SHOOTER?
>> Reporter: YOU KNOW, WOLF, THE
ONE THING WE ALL HAVE TO KEEP IN
MIND IS THAT MUCH OF THE
FORENSIC EVIDENCE AS TO WHY THIS
HAPPENED, THE ENTIRE MOTIVE IS
PROBABLY LOCKED SOMEWHERE IN
THIS HOUSE.
THIS IS ONE OF THE FIRST PLACES
THAT POLICE CAME TO IMMEDIATELY
AFTER THE SHOOTING.
THEY ALLEGEDLY FOUND A COMPUTER.
THERE ARE REPORTS THAT, IN FACT,
THE COMPUTER WAS SMASHED.
THE QUESTION IS IS WHEN WAS THAT
COMPUTER SMASHED?
WAS IT SMASHED BEFORE THIS WHOLE
SHOOTING SPREE BEGAN, OR WAS IT
WHAT PROMPTED HIM?
AND THAT'S SOMETHING THAT
INVESTIGATORS ARE GOING TO BE
LOOKING INTO.
WHILE THE STATE POLICE WOULD NOT
CONFIRM, THEY SAID THEY DON'T
TALK ABOUT EVIDENCE, WHAT THEY
DID SAY IS THAT THEY'VE GOT AN
EXCELLENT FORENSIC TEAM THAT'S
GOING TO LOOK INTO ELECTRONIC
DATA.
THAT'S PRETTY MUCH AS FAR AS
THEY'LL GO.
THE QUESTION IS WHY.
FIRST OF ALL, POLICE ALSO SAY
THERE WAS NO DIRECT CONNECTION
WITH THE SCHOOL.
THE GUNMAN HAD NO DIRECT
CONNECTION WITH THE NEWTOWN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
SO WHY DID HE GO THERE?
THAT IS ONE OF THE MYSTERIES
LOCKED IN HIS MIND.
WHAT WE DO KNOW IS THAT THERE
WAS SOME MOVEMENT IN THE LANZA
FAMILY, IN WHAT WAS GOING ON IN
THE HOME BECAUSE WE NOW FIND OUT
THAT THE MOTHER APPARENTLY HAD
MADE COMMENTS TO FRIENDS THAT
SHE WAS -- THAT THIS WAS GOING
TO BE HER LAST WINTER HERE, THAT
SHE WAS PLANNING ON MOVING,
GETTING AWAY FROM HERE.
AGAIN, WHY?
NOBODY KNOWS.
POLICE WILL NOT BE ABLE TO
OBVIOUSLY FIND THE ANSWERS SINCE
SHE WAS FOUND SHOT DEAD IN THE
HEAD INSIDE THIS HOME.
AND, OF COURSE, THE MYSTERIES
THERE, THEY JUST SORT OF KEEP ON
COMING, WOLF, AS EVERYBODY TRIES
TO WORK THROUGH THEIR GRIEF AND
BURY THE CHILDREN AND THE
TEACHERS WHO WERE VICTIMS OF ALL
THIS, WOLF.
>> Reporter: DEB, INVESTIGATORS
ARE TALKING TO PEOPLE WHO KNEW
ADAM LANZA, THE SHOOTER.
TELL US ABOUT THAT.
>> Reporter: WHAT'S SO
INTERESTING IS USUALLY AFTER A
SHOOTING LIKE THIS, A LOT OF
INFORMATION COMES OUT ON THE
GUNMAN, WHY HE DID IT.
BUT THE INFORMATION THAT WE HAVE
ABOUT HIM IS THAT APPARENTLY HE
DID NOT GO TO THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
HE DID GO TO SOME HIGH SCHOOLS
HERE IN THE AREA, BUT IT SEEMS
LIKE THERE WAS A LOT OF
TURNOVER, THAT HE WAS GOING TO A
NUMBER OF SCHOOLS HERE.
AND AT ONE OF THE SCHOOLS THAT
HE WENT TO, HE WAS ASSIGNED A
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST BECAUSE NOT
THAT THEY WERE WORRIED ABOUT HIM
AS A THREAT TO WORRY STUDENTS.
IN FACT, THEY WERE MORE WORRIED
THAT OTHER STUDENTS WOULD BE
PICKING ON HIM.
SO THAT'S WHY HE WAS ASSIGNED TO
THAT.
AGAIN, HIS DEMEANOR VERY QUIET,
VERY SORT OF, YOU KNOW,
ANTI-SOCIAL.
AND YOU TALK TO SO MANY PEOPLE.
A RELATIVE WILL SAY ADAM LANZA
WAS A BRILLIANT KID, THAT HE WAS
A REALLY SMART KID, BUT THEY
CAN'T TELL YOU OTHER DETAILS
ABOUT HIM.
HE WAS A COMPUTER GEEK, BUT THEY
CAN'T TELL YOU IF HE LOVED
SPORTS.
SO DETAILS LIKE THAT ARE
MISSING.
AND TO FIND SOMEBODY WHO
ACTUALLY KNEW ADAM LANZA AND WHO
CAN TALK ABOUT ADAM IN HIS LATER
YEARS, THAT IS REALLY WHAT'S SO
DIFFICULT.
AND THAT'S WHY INVESTIGATORS ARE
HOPING THAT THE INFORMATION THAT
THEY SEIZED FROM INSIDE THE
HOUSE, I DON'T KNOW IF YOU CAN
SEE IT, BUT THERE IS A POLICE
OFFICER STANDING THERE AT THE
FRONT OF THE DOOR.
AGAIN, THIS IS STILL A CRIME
SCENE.
THEY'RE STILL GOING THROUGH IT.
IF THEY CAN GET A LOT OF THE
INFORMATION FROM THE COMPUTER,
THEN PERHAPS, WOLF, WE WILL HAVE
AN ANSWER.
>> Reporter: A LOT OF QUESTIONS
AND STILL ONLY A FEW ANSWERS.
DEB FEYERICK, THANK YOU.
THE SHOOTING HAS CERTAINLY MANY
PARENTS WONDERING HOW TO EXPLAIN
ALL OF THIS, THIS GREAT TRAGEDY
TO THEIR OWN CHILDREN.
WE'RE GOING TO TALK WITH A
PSYCHOLOGIST ABOUT HOW TO DO
JUST THAT AS WE CONTINUE OUR
SPECIAL COVERAGE.
>>> THESE MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS
ARE COMING UP ALL OVER NEWTOWN
HERE.
YOU CAN SEE PEOPLE ARE JUST
BRINGING TEDDY BEARS, THEY'RE
BRINGING FLOWERS, LITTLE BELLS,
AS YOU CAN SEE OVER THERE, EVEN
LEGOS TO REMEMBER THE VICTIMS
FROM NEWTOWN, WHAT'S GOING ON.
ASHLEIGH BANFIELD IS ALSO
REMEMBERING WHAT'S GOING ON.
SHE HAS A CLOSER LOOK AT ONE OF
THESE MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS NEAR A
SCHOOL.
>> Reporter: IT DIDN'T TAKE LONG
BEFORE THIS COMMUNITY BEGAN TO
START BRINGING CHRISTMAS TREES
TO WHAT'S BECOME A MAKESHIFT
MEMORIAL NOT FAR FROM THE
SCHOOL.
AND THERE ARE MORE THAN 20 OF
THESE DECORATED TREES.
EACH ONE OF THEM WITH STUFFED
ANIMALS AND CANDY CANES AND BOWS
AND NAMES AND FLOWERS.
WHAT YOU SEE MOSTLY IS THE
REPETITION OF 20, AT LEAST 20,
WHETHER IT'S CANDLES THAT ARE
BROUGHT OUT, THEY'RE OUT OUT IN
COLLECTIONS OF 20 TO REPRESENT
THESE VICTIMS.
YOU ALSO SEE THE FLOWERS THAT
HAVE BEEN BROUGHT OUT FROM LOCAL
FLORISTS.
IT'S JUST REMARKABLE THAT THE
SHEER NUMBER OF TEDDY BEARS THAT
ARE HERE AND STUFFED ANIMALS.
IF YOU NOTICE UP HERE, ONE OF
THE PERMANENT PILLARS SOMEONE
HAS BROUGHT OUT ANGEL WINGS.
AND THERE'S A SIGN BELOW SAYING
"WE PROMISE TO NEVER FORGET
YOU."
JUST MOVING A LITTLE BIT FARTHER
ON, YOU SEE THE REAL COLLECTION
OF WHERE THIS MAKESHIFT MEMORIAL
STARTED.
THERE'S A TENT NOW, BUT
EVERYTHING IS SO WET FROM THE
RAIN.
THERE'S JUST HUNDREDS OF TEDDY
BEARS AND FLOWERS AND MESSAGES
AND CANDLES.
THE ONES THAT ARE STILL BURNING
ARE NOW UNDER THE TENT.
AND IF YOU LOOK UP HERE, YOU'LL
SEE WHY.
THIS IS THE PERMANENT SIGN FOR
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
IT'S JUST BEYOND HERE.
>> CHILDREN IN NEWTOWN AND
CITIES NEARBY ARE STILL OFF OF
SCHOOL TODAY, BUT FOR THE REST
OF THE COUNTRY, SCHOOL BELLS
RANG THIS MORNING.
PARENTS AND TEACHERS STILL
STRUGGLING, PROBABLY GOING TO
STRUGGLE FOR A WHILE NOW.
HOW DO THEY EXPLAIN THIS MASS
SHOOTING AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
AND WHETHER OR NOT THIS COULD
EVEN HAPPEN AT THEIR OWN CHILD'S
SCHOOL.
HERE'S WHAT ONE DAD SAID ON
FRIDAY.
>> MY KIDS ARE ALREADY ASKING,
WHEN IS THIS GOING TO HAPPEN
AGAIN?
YOU KNOW, IT WAS ONLY A WEEK AGO
THAT WE WERE TALKING ABOUT THIS
TYPE OF SITUATION.
AND I SAID THE CHANCES OF IT
HAPPENING ARE 1 IN A ZILLION AT
SANDY HOOK.
I WAS WRONG ABOUT THAT.
>> I'M JOINED AGAIN FROM NEW
YORK BY CLINICAL PSYCHOLOGIST
JEFF GARDERE.
AND JEFF, WE MIGHT HAVE TO
INTERRUPT YOU IF THE WHITE HOUSE
BRIEFING STARTS.
>> SURE.
>> TO GO TO THAT.
BUT IN THE MEANTIME, LET'S TALK
ABOUT THIS.
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
THERE ARE KIDS ALL OVER THE
COUNTRY, THEY'RE GETTING BITS
AND PIECES OF THIS STORY.
THEY'RE PROBABLY AFRAID.
THEY'RE PROBABLY VERY UPSET.
HOW SHOULD PARENTS COMMUNICATE
AND REASSURE THEM THAT IT'S OKAY
TO GO TO SCHOOL?
>> WELL, FIRST AND FOREMOST,
SUZANNE, WE'VE GOT TO LET THE
KIDS KNOW THAT YES, THEY ARE
SAFE.
THERE ARE NO GUARANTEES IN LIFE
AT ALL.
BUT THEY ARE SAFE IN THEIR
SCHOOLS.
AND THE WAY THAT WE CAN DO THAT
IS TAKING THEM TO SCHOOL,
SPENDING SOME TIME WITH THEM AND
CERTAINLY THE TEACHERS HAVE TO
SPEND THE TIME HUGGING THEM AND
TALKING TO THEM AND REASSURING
THEM IN ADDITION, OF COURSE, TO
THEIR LEARNING THEIR LESSONS OF
THE DAY.
SECONDLY, I JUST THINK IT'S
IMPORTANT THAT WE LISTEN TO OUR
CHILDREN.
IT'S NOT ABOUT LECTURING TO
THEM, BUT KNOWING WHERE THEY
ARE, ASKING THEM, JUST THROWING
OUT LITTLE BITS OF INFORMATION
AND TRY TO PULL THEM IN AND SEE
WHERE THEY ARE COMING FROM.
WHAT THEIR ISSUES ARE, WHAT THE
ANXIETY OR THE FEAR MAY BE.
>> JEFF, SHOULD THERE BE A PLAN?
SHOULD YOU ARM YOUR CHILD WITH A
LITTLE EMERGENCY PLAN TO HELP
REASSURE THEM IF THERE IS A
SITUATION THAT IS AS TRAGIC AS
THAT, OR IF THEY FEEL THREATENED
IN SOME WAY LIKE THEY USED TO
TEACH US NOT TO TALK TO
STRANGERS AND THAT KIND OF
THING?
>> SURE.
>> WHAT CAN YOU DO IN A
PRACTICAL SENSE?
>> SUZANNE, I REALLY LIKE THAT
EMPOWERMENT IDEA, AND THAT'S
WHAT I'M CALLING IT.
BECAUSE WE KNOW THE OPPOSITE OF
ANXIETY IS ACTION.
AND SO BY GIVING THEM A PLAN, BY
GIVING THEM SOME INFORMATION ON
A PIECE OF PAPER WHO TO CALL,
WHERE THEY SHOULD GO, WHAT ARE
THE SAFE HAVENS, ALL OF THOSE
THINGS TAKE A LOT OF THAT
PSYCHOLOGICAL ENERGY AWAY FROM
WORRYING AND MORE TOWARDS BEING
EMPOWERED AND DOING SOMETHING
POSITIVE.
>> HOW DO YOU KNOW IF YOUR CHILD
IS NOT DOING WELL WITH THIS?
>> WELL, IT'S VERY DIFFICULT TO
TELL BECAUSE I WILL TELL YOU AS
A FATHER OF MANY CHILDREN AND
HAVE LITTLE CHILDREN, WHEN I
ASKED THEM ABOUT IT, THEY DIDN'T
REALLY WANT TO TALK.
THEY WERE VERY SILENT ABOUT IT.
SUFFERING SILENTLY.
SO IT'S IMPORTANT THAT WE
REALIZE IT'S NOT ABOUT THEIR
BEING SO RESILIENT IF THEY DON'T
WANT TO TALK.
IT SIMPLY IS THAT THEY ARE
PROCESSING IT AND THEREFORE WE
CAN DO THINGS LIKE GET THEM TO
DRAW AND PLAY.
BUT WE'LL ALSO SEE THEY'LL TRY
TO AVOID SCHOOL.
>> ALL RIGHT, JEFF, I'M SORRY, I
HAVE TO INTERRUPT.
WE HAVE JAY CARNEY AT THE WHITE
HOUSE SPEAKING ON THIS.
LET'S LISTEN IN.
>> -- USING THE POWER OF HIS
OFFICE TO PUSH FOR TIGHTER GUN
CONTROL?
>> I APPRECIATE THE QUESTION.
THE PRESIDENT SPOKE LAST NIGHT
AT THE VIGIL IN NEWTOWN.
AND HE SPOKE ABOUT THE FACT THAT
THE FAMILIES OF NEWTOWN ARE NOT
ALONE.
AND HE ALSO SPOKE ABOUT THE FACT
THAT THE KIND OF VIOLENCE THAT
OCCURRED IN NEWTOWN OCCURS TOO
OFTEN.
IN THIS COUNTRY, ALTHOUGH WHAT
WE SAW IN NEWTOWN WAS
PARTICULARLY HORRIFIC.
HE SAID THAT IN THE COMING
WEEKS, HE WOULD USE THE POWER OF
HIS OFFICE TO ENGAGE THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE AND LAWMAKERS,
LAW ENFORCEMENT, MENTAL HEALTH
EXPERTS, EDUCATORS AND OTHERS IN
AN EFFORT TO TRY TO PREVENT
THESE KINDS OF TERRIBLE
TRAGEDIES FROM HAPPENING IN THE
FUTURE.
IT'S A COMPLEX PROBLEM THAT WILL
REQUIRE A COMPLEX SOLUTION.
NO SINGLE PIECE OF LEGISLATION,
NO SINGLE ACTION WILL FULLY
ADDRESS THE PROBLEM.
SO I DON'T HAVE A SPECIFIC
AGENDA TO ANNOUNCE TO YOU TODAY.
I WOULD SIMPLY POINT YOU TO WHAT
THE PRESIDENT SAID LAST NIGHT
ABOUT MOVING FORWARD IN COMING
WEEKS.
AND I WOULD LOOK FOR HIM TO DO
THAT.
>> AND THE COMPREHENSIVE
SOLUTION, DO YOU THINK IT'S FAIR
AND ACCURATE TO SAY THAT
ADDRESSING GUN VIOLENCE, GUN
CONTROL WOULD HAVE TO BE PART OF
IT?
>> I THINK THAT IT'S PART OF IT,
BUT IT IS FAR FROM ALL OF IT.
AND AS YOU KNOW, THE PRESIDENT
HAS TAKEN POSITIONS ON
COMMON-SENSE MEASURES THAT HE
BELIEVES SHOULD BE TAKEN TO HELP
ADDRESS THIS PROBLEM, BUT HE
MADE CLEAR THAT MORE NEEDS TO BE
DONE, THAT WE AS A NATION HAVE
NOT DONE ENOUGH, CLEARLY, TO
FULFILL OUR NUMBER ONE
OBLIGATION, WHICH IS TO PROTECT
OUR CHILDREN.
>> ONE MORE ON THIS.
AS YOU KNOW, WE'VE SEEN THESE
HORRIFIC MOMENTS COME AND GO AND
THAT THE DEBATE ABOUT GUN
SAFETY, CHILDREN'S SAFETY, GOES
WITH IT.
DOES THE PRESIDENT THINK THAT HE
NEEDS TO CAPITALIZE ON THIS, GET
THIS CONVERSATION GOING AND SEE
SOME ACTION IN THE SHORT TERM,
OR DOES HE FEEL LIKE HE CAN GET
THROUGH THE FISCAL CLIFF,
IMMIGRATION AND THERE'S NOW A
MINDSET AND A WILL TO GET THIS
DONE MONTHS DOWN THE LINE?
>> I DON'T HAVE A SPECIFIC TIME
LINE FOR YOU FOR WHAT THE
PRESIDENT WILL DO MOVING
FORWARD.
I WOULD SIMPLY REFER YOU TO HIS
REMARKS LAST NIGHT WHEN HE
TALKED ABOUT THE ACTION HE HOPED
TO TAKE TO ENGAGE THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE IN THE COMING WEEKS.
I THINK THAT WHAT HAPPENED AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HAS
CLEARLY SHOCKED THE ENTIRE
NATION.
AND HAS LAID BARE THE NECESSITY
OF EVALUATING THE VARIOUS THINGS
THAT WE CAN AND MUST DO AS A
NATION TO TRY TO BETTER PRODUCT
OUR CHILDREN.
>> QUICKLY ON FISCAL CLIFF, THE
PRESIDENT SAID TO THE BUSINESS
ROUNDTABLE RECENTLY THAT
REPUBLICANS NEED TO REACH WHAT
HE CALLED A CONCEPTUAL
BREAKTHROUGH ON RATES, TAX RATES
GOING UP, AND THEN ONCE THAT
HAPPENS, THAT YOU HAVE TO COME
TOGETHER PRETTY QUICKLY.
DOES HE FEEL HE HAS HA NOW THAT
SPEAKER BOEHNER, HE IS TALKING
ABOUT RATES IN THE CONVERSATION?
>> I WON'T COMMENT ON SPECIFIC
REPORTED PROPOSALS OR
COUNTERPROPOSALS ON INTERNAL
CONVERSATIONS BETWEEN THE
PRESIDENT AND THE SPEAKER OR THE
PRESIDENT'S TEAM AND THE
SPEAKER'S TEAM OR WITH OTHER
MEMBERS OF LEADERSHIP.
THE PRESIDENT'S INSISTENCE THAT
RATES NEED TO GO UP ON THE TOP
2% WAS BASED ON AN ECONOMIC
REALITY, WHICH IS THAT IN ORDER
TO ACHIEVE A BROAD DEFICIT
REDUCTION PACKAGE THAT PUTS OUR
ECONOMY ON A SUSTAINABLE FISCAL
PATH IN THE FUTURE, A CERTAIN
LEVEL OF REVENUE GLEANED FROM
THE WEALTHY HAS TO BE MET.
AND THE ONLY WAY TO DO THAT WAS
THROUGH, IN PART, RATES RISING.
THAT REMAINS HIS POSITION.
SO WE HAVE SEEN SINCE THE
ELECTION A CHANGE IN TONE AND IN
SOME CASES A CHANGE IN POSITION
FROM DIFFERENT ROEPUBLICANS
INCLUDING ELECTED REPUBLICANS ON
THE ISSUE OF FIRST REVENUE AND
THEN ACKNOWLEDGING THAT RATES
HAVE TO GO UP.
BUT THUS FAR, THE PRESIDENT'S
PROPOSAL IS THE ONLY PROPOSAL
THAT WE HAVE SEEN THAT ACHIEVES
THE BALANCE THAT'S SO NECESSARY.
AND THE BALANCE IS IMPORTANT
BECAUSE A PLAN THAT DOES NOT
HAVE IT PUTS UNDULY THE BURDEN
ON SENIOR CITIZENS.
THROUGH -- OR ON MIDDLE-CLASS
AMERICANS OR ON PARENTS WITH
DISABLED CHILDREN.
AND THAT IS NOT ACCEPTABLE.
BALANCE IS ESSENTIAL BECAUSE IN
ORDER TO MOVE FORWARD IN A WAY
THAT PROTECTS THE MIDDLE CLASS,
WE NEED TO HAVE THE PACKAGE
INCLUDE THE KIND OF REVENUE THAT
THE PRESIDENT HAS TALKED ABOUT.
>> LAST QUESTION.
THE PRESIDENT CAMPAIGNED ON
TAXES GOING UP ON HOUSEHOLDS
OVER $250,000.
HE WAS VERY CLEAR AND SPECIFIC
ABOUT THAT.
WHEN YOU WERE ASKED ABOUT THAT
THRESHOLD OVER THE SUMMER, YOU
SAID THE PRESIDENT'S POSITION
HAS BEEN THE SAME FOR A LONG,
LONG TIME.
IT HAS NOT CHANGED AND IT WILL
NOT CHANGE.
I KNOW YOU DON'T WANT TO TALK
ABOUT THE BOEHNER PROPOSAL OF $1
MILLION, BUT I'M JUST ASKING
ABOUT THE PRESIDENT'S STANCE.
IS IT STILL AND WILL REMAIN THAT
$250,000 IS THE THRESHOLD?
>> WELL, I WILL SAY WHAT I'VE
SAID MANY TIMES FROM HERE IN
RECENT WEEKS AND MONTHS, WHICH
IS THAT THE ONLY PLAN THAT WE
HAVE SEEN THAT ACHIEVES THE SIZE
AND THE BALANCE THAT'S REQUIRED
FOR SUSTAINABLE -- FOR LONG-TERM
DEFICIT REDUCTION AND PUTTING
OUR ECONOMY ON A SUSTAINABLE
FISCAL PATH IS THE PRESIDENT'S.
AND AN ELEMENT -- IMPORTANT
ELEMENT OF THAT ON THE REVENUE
SIDE IS ALLOWING CURRENT LAW,
WHEN IT COMES TO THE TOP 2%, TO
REMAIN IN PLACE, WHICH WOULD SEE
RATES ON THOSE WEALTHY AMERICANS
RISE EVEN AS WE EXTEND AND IN
THE PRESIDENT'S MIND MAKE
PERMANENT TAX CUTS FOR 98% OF
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE, FOR THE
OTHER 98% OF THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE.
THAT'S THE PRESIDENT'S POSITION.
AND AGAIN, IT'S NOT, AS I'VE
SAID REPEATEDLY, HIS POSITION IS
NOT BASED ON THE NOTION THAT
THESE RATES HAVE TO GO UP
BECAUSE THAT'S GOOD IN AND OF
ITSELF.
IT'S BASED ON THE NECESSITY OF
HAVING ENOUGH REVENUE --
>> PRESS SECRETARY JAY CARNEY
WEIGHING IN ON BOTH ISSUES HERE,
VERY IMPORTANT, OF COURSE, THE
FISCAL CLIFF, THE NEGOTIATIONS
THAT CONTINUE BETWEEN THE
PRESIDENT AND HOUSE SPEAKER
BOEHNER.
THE TWO LEADERS MEETING EARLIER
TODAY AT THE WHITE HOUSE TO
DISCUSS IT.
JAY CARNEY SAYING THAT THERE IS
SOME ROOM, SOME WIGGLE ROOM, IF
YOU WILL, THAT THE GOP
REPUBLICANS GIVING A LITTLE BIT
MORE HERE, PERHAPS EVEN TAX
INCREASES FOR THOSE WHO ARE
MAKING MORE THAN $1 MILLION, BUT
NOT LESS THAN THAT.
AND ALSO WEIGHING IN AS WELL ON
THE TRAGEDY THAT OCCURRED, THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING, THE MASSACRE
THERE, SAYING MORE MUST BE DONE.
WE DON'T HAVE SPECIFICS ON HOW
THE WHITE HOUSE IS GOING TO MOVE
THAT DEBATE FORWARD, BUT THAT
THEY ARE ENGAGED.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A LOOK AT
BOTH SIDES OF THE GUN CONTROL
DEBATE RIGHT AFTER A QUICK
BREAK.
AK.
I'M GOING TO DREAM
ABOUT THAT TIRAMISU.
WHAT A NIGHT, HUH?
BUT, UM, CAN THE TEST DRIVE
BE OVER NOW?
HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A PASSAT.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN, $0 DUE AT SIGNING,
$0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
PROGRESSIVE DIRECT AND OTHER
CAR INSURANCE COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
CALL OR CLICK TODAY.
>>> CALL FOR MORE GUN CONTROL IN
THE AFTERMATH OF FRIDAY'S
DEVASTATING ATTACK IS SPREADING
FROM ONLINE PETITIONS TO MEMBERS
OF CONGRESS WHO ARE NOW
PROPOSING NEW BILLS.
THESE ARE THE TYPE OF GUNS
POLICE SAY 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM
LANZA HAD ON HIM WHEN HE
ATTACKED SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL ON FRIDAY.
POLICE SAY LANZA USED A
SEMI-AUTOMATIC GUN LIKE THE ONE
AT THE BOTTOM OF THE SCREEN TO
FIRE MULTIPLE MAGAZINES, EACH
CONTAINING 30 BULLETS.
ACCORDING TO "THE NEW YORK
TIMES," THIS IS THE SAME TYPE OF
ASSAULT RIFLE USED IN THE OREGON
MALL SHOOTING AND THE COLORADO
THEATER KILLINGS.
VAN JONES IS A CNN CONTRIBUTOR,
FORMER SPECIAL ADVISER TO THE
PRESIDENT.
AND VAN, GOOD TO SEE YOU.
I KNOW YOU'RE WEIGHING IN ON
THIS.
YOU SENT OUT A LOT OF TWEETS.
YOU'VE GOT A CONSERVATIVE
DEMOCRAT WEST VIRGINIA SENATOR
JOE MANCHIN TODAY WHO SAYS LOOK,
THERE NEEDS TO BE A DISCUSSION,
A SERIOUS DISCUSSION, ABOUT
WHETHER OR NOT WE NEED
ASSAULT-TYPE WEAPONS ON THE
STREET OR WHETHER OR NOT THEY
SHOULD BE BANNED.
ON THE OTHER HAND, YOU'VE GOT A
GROUP -- THE MICHIGAN COALITION
FOR RESPONSIBLE GUN OWNERS
ARGUING THAT ACTUALLY HAVING A
GUN SAVES PEOPLE'S LIVES.
HERE'S WHAT HE SAYS.
>> THE SHOOTER IN THE MALL IN
OREGON WAS CONFRONTED BY A
LEGALLY ARMED CITIZEN WHO
POINTED HIS GUN AT THE SHOOTER
AND THEN DECIDED NOT TO SQUEEZE
THE TRIGGER BECAUSE HE WAS
AFRAID OF MISSING AND HITTING
BYSTANDERS.
HE WAS ACTING VERY RESPONSIBLY.
AND THE NEXT SHOT THAT THAT
SHOOTER FIRED THAT THE KILLER
FIRED WAS ON HIMSELF AFTER HE
WAS CONFRONTED WITH AN ARMED
CITIZEN.
SO THAT'S ACTUALLY ONE EXAMPLE
OF A RESPONSIBLE GUN OWNER USING
A GUN TO SAVE LIVES.
>> VAN, WHERE DO YOU FUALL ON
THIS?
BECAUSE THEY MAKE THE CASE ON
BOTH SIDES.
ON ONE HAND, IT IS A VERY
DANGEROUS SITUATION TO HAVE
PEOPLE ARMED.
ON THE OTHER HAND, IT DOES SAVE
LIVES IN SOME CIRCUMSTANCES.
>> WELL, FIRST OF ALL, NOBODY IS
SAYING THAT, YOU KNOW, ALL
PEOPLE SHOULD GIVE UP ALL THEIR
G
GUNS, BUT PEOPLE ARE TIRED NOW.
WE'RE TIRED -- IT'S NOT JUST
THESE CHILDREN, THERE ARE
FUNERALS ALL ACROSS THE COUNTRY
EVERY DAY.
WE'RE TIRED TO GOING TO FUNERALS
IN CHICAGO.
WE'RE TIRED OF GOING TO FUNERALS
IN OAKLAND.
WE'RE TIRED OF SEEING YOUNG
PEOPLE IN CASKETS AND OLD FOLKS
LIKE MYSELF SITTING UP IN THE
PEWS.
PEOPLE ARE TIRED.
AND A MAJORITY OF THE NRA
MEMBERSHIP, NOT THE LEADERSHIP,
NOT THE PEOPLE WHO JUMP ON
TELEVISION, BUT EVEN THE
MAJORITY OF THE NRA MEMBERSHIP
SAYS COMMON SENSE SAYS YOU DON'T
NEED A 100-CLIP -- THESE
MEGACLIPS FOR PEOPLE TO GO
HUNTING.
WE CAN DO SOMETHING NOW.
IN AUSTRALIA, PEOPLE KEEP
SAYING, YOU CAN'T DO ANYTHING
ABOUT THIS, IT WILL HAPPEN
ANYWAY.
BUT IN AUSTRALIA, WHEN THEY HAD
A HAS KERR THAT WAS HORRIBLE,
THE GOVERNMENT SAID ENOUGH IS
ENOUGH.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO HAVE THESE
MILITARY-STYLE WEAPONS.
WE'LL HAVE A BUYBACK.
HOMICIDES AND SUICIDES FELL BY
HALF IN AUS TRAIL WHICH IS ALSO
A DEMOCRACY.
SO PEOPLE ARE TIRED.
I'M SORRY, GO AHEAD.
>> LET ME INTERRUPT IF I MAY.
WHAT DO YOU THINK THAT THE WHITE
HOUSE, THE RESPONSIBILITY OF THE
WHITE HOUSE IS?
BECAUSE WE KNOW AFTER THE GABBY
GIFFORDS SHOOTING IN 2011, THE
JUSTICE DEPARTMENT DREW UP PLANS
AND STEPS.
THEY WANTED TO EXPAND BACKGROUND
CHECKS SO THAT THE GUNS WOULD
NOT FALL IN THE HANDS OF
MENTALLY ILL FOLKS OR CRIMINALS.
THEY SCRAP IT HAD DURING THE
CAMPAIGN.
IT WAS JUST TOO HOT OF AN ISSUE.
WHAT DO YOU WANT THE WHITE HOUSE
TO DO NOW?
>> WELL, WE'VE ALL BEEN TOO
COWARDLY.
I'VE BEEN ON YOUR SHOW MANY
TIMES.
I'VE NEVER MENTIONED THIS IN
PUBLIC.
ALL OF US HAVE BEEN TOO
COWARDLY, REPUBLICANS,
DEMOCRATS, GUN OWNERS, EVERYONE,
WE BEND TOO COWARDLY.
I THINK WE'VE GOT TO NOW SAY WE
CANNOT HAVE THIS BECOME THE NEW
NORMAL.
WE CANNOT ADAPT TO ABSURDITY.
LET'S LOOK WHERE THE CHON GROUND
IS.
FIRST OF ALL, THERE'S GOOD NEWS.
REPUBLICANS AND DEMOCRATS ARE
NOW SAYING THAT HEALTH CARE IS
VERY IMPORTANT.
YOU HAVEN'T HEARD THAT
DISCUSSION.
LET'S USE THAT TO PUSH FORWARD
MORE SUPPORT FOR HEALTH CARE.
YOU'VE GOT REPUBLICANS AND
DEMOCRATS SAYING WE DON'T WANT
THESE MILITARY-STYLE MEGACLIPS
OUT THERE.
LET'S MOVE ON THAT.
THE PRESIDENT RAN IN 2008 ON
PUTTING THE ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN
BACK IN PLACE.
LET'S AT LEAST GO BACK TO THE
COMMON SENSE THAT WE HAD BEFORE.
THERE'S AN OPPORTUNITY TO DO
SOMETHING, BUT THE IDEA THAT THE
LEADERSHIP, NOT THE MEMBERS OF
THE NRA, I'M A SOUTHERNER.
I BELIEVE IN THE SECOND
AMENDMENT.
BUT THAT THE MEMBERSHIP OF THE
NRA CAN'T HAVE ITS DESIRES HEARD
BECAUSE OF SOME GUN EXTREMISTS,
THOSE DAYS ARE OVER.
>> AND VAN, DO YOU THINK THE
PRESIDENT SHOULD USE EXECUTIVE
ORDER TO GET SOME THINGS DONE
HERE, TO PUSH SOME THINGS
THROUGH, TO FORCE IT THROUGH?
>> WELL, I THINK HE SHOULD DO
EVERYTHING THAT HE CAN DO.
I THINK THE DEPARTMENT OF
JUSTICE SHOULD BE MUCH TOUGHER
ON PEOPLE WHO ARE NOT SUPPOSED
TO BE GETTING THESE GUNS, WHO
ARE TRYING TO GET THESE GUNS.
BUT WE DO NEED TO HAVE CONGRESS
TAKE ACTION.
AND I'M SO PROUD OF SENATOR
MANCHIN, SENATOR FEINSTEIN FOR
STEPPING UP TO THE PLATE, AND
REPUBLICANS AND DEMOCRATS COULD
BE UNITED ON THIS NOW.
>> ALL RIGHT, VAN JONES, THANK
YOU.
WE'LL TAKE A LOOK AT THE OTHER
SIDE OF THE ARGUMENT.
WE'LL TALK TO OREGON STATE
REPRESENTATIVE DENNIS RICHARDSON
WHO IS CALLING FOR SCHOOLS TO
ARM THE TEACHERS.
[ sniffs ] I HAVE A COLD.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
♪
BECOMING
PART OF THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
TREES WILL TALK TO NETWORKS
WILL TALK TO SCIENTISTS
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE.
CARS WILL TALK TO ROAD SENSORS
WILL TALK TO STOPLIGHTS
ABOUT TRAFFIC EFFICIENCY.
THE AMBULANCE WILL TALK
TO PATIENT RECORDS
WILL TALK TO DOCTORS
ABOUT SAVING LIVES.
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
THE NEXT BIG THING?
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
♪
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
♪
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
Progresso.
In what world do potatoes,
bacon and cheese
add up to 100 calories?
Your world.
♪
[ whispers ]
Real bacon...
Creamy cheese...
100 calories...
[ Chef ] Ma'am
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
>>> SO AFTER THE DEVASTATING
SCHOOL SHOOTING ON FRIDAY,
OREGON STATE REPRESENTATIVE
DENNIS RICHARDSON WROTE AN
E-MAIL TO HIS STATE SCHOOL
SUPERINTENDENT SAYING THAT GUN
BANS ON SCHOOL PROPERTY SHOULD
BE OVERTURNED.
DENNIS RICHARDSON IS JOINING US
FROM MEDFORD, OREGON.
GOOD TO HAVE YOU HERE.
FIRST OF ALL, I WANT TO JUST
THROW OUT THIS QUOTE THAT YOU
GAVE TO THE A.P. SO EVERYBODY IS
AWARE OF YOUR POSITION.
YOU SAY "IF I HAD BEEN A TEACHER
OR THE PRINCIPAL AT THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND IF
THE SCHOOL DISTRICT DID NOT
PRECLUDE ME FROM HAVING ACCESS
TO A FIREARM, EITHER BY
CONCEALED CARRY OR LOCKED IN MY
DESK, MOST OF THE MURDERED
CHILDREN WOULD STILL BE ALIVE,
AND THE GUNMAN WOULD STILL BE
DEAD, AND NOT BY SUICIDE."
SO EXPLAIN YOUR POSITION HERE.
MORE GUNS IN THE SCHOOL?
ARMED TEACHERS?
HOW DOES THAT HELP?
>> WELL, IT'S BEEN 13 YEARS
SINCE THE TRAGEDY IN COLUMBINE.
ALMOST 6 YEARS SINCE VIRGINIA
TECH, AND NOW WE ALL MOURN THE
MASSACRE THAT OCCURRED IN
CONNECTICUT LAST FRIDAY.
WE CANNOT CONTINUE TO BE PASSIVE
WHEN THE ONLY PERSON WHO'S ARMED
IN A SCHOOL SHOOTING SITUATION
IS THE SHOOTER HIMSELF, THE
PSYCHOPATH.
WHAT I'M SUGGESTING IS THAT WE
SET UP --
>> OKAY, GO AHEAD.
I'M SORRY.
>> WHAT I'M SUGGESTING IS THAT
WE HAVE CAMPUS RESPONDERS, TWO
OR THREE VOLUNTEERS, THAT ARE ON
THE STAFF, WHETHER
ADMINISTRATORS OR TEACHERS OR
STAFF MEMBERS HOPEFULLY MAYBE
PRIOR MILITARY, PRIOR LAW
ENFORCEMENT, BUT PEOPLE WHO ARE
TRAINED WHO WILL BE ARMED AND
WHEN THE FIRST SHOT IS FIRED ON
THE NEXT CAMPUS, THEY CAN
RESPOND AND MEET LETHAL FORCE
WITH LETHAL FORCE.
>> DENNIS, A LOT OF STUDIES HAVE
BEEN DONE THAT WHEN YOU HAVE
MORE GUNS IN PEOPLE'S HANDS, SO
MANY ACCIDENTS HAPPEN, MISFIRES,
PEOPLE GET AHOLD OF THESE GUNS
EVEN IF THEY TRY TO PUT THEM IN
A SAFE PLACE AND LOCK THEM UP,
THAT IT ONLY TURNS TO MORE
VIOLENCE.
I MEAN, HOW WOULD YOU ACTUALLY
CONTROL OR PREVENT SOMETHING
LIKE THAT FROM HAPPENING IF YOU
INTRODUCE WEAPONS INSIDE OF A
SCHOOL?
>> WELL, BY HAVING -- BY TAKING
SAFETY MEASURES.
FIRST YOU MAKE SURE THAT THOSE
WHO ARE YOUR CAMPUS RESPONDERS
ARE TRAINED.
SECONDLY, YOU MAKE SURE THAT THE
WEAPONS ARE NOT EASILY
ACCESSIBLE.
I MEAN, THERE ARE METAL
CONTAINERS THAT REQUIRE A CODE
BEFORE THEY CAN BE OPENED.
SO WE CAN SECURE THE WEAPON.
BUT WHAT WE CAN'T DO IS JUST
ALLOW US TO CONTINUE TO TAKE A
PASSIVE APPROACH.
THE ASSAULT WEAPON THAT WAS USED
IN CONNECTICUT IS ALREADY BANNED
IN CONNECTICUT.
THE TEACHERS ALREADY WERE
TRAINED IN LOCKDOWN.
THAT'S A PASSIVE RESPONSE.
WE OWE IT TO OUR CHILDREN AND
OUR EDUCATORS TO ENSURE THAT WE
HAVE THE ABILITY TO RESPOND IN
EVERY SCHOOL WITH LETHAL FORCE
IN AN EVENT OF SUCH A SHOOTING
IN THE FUTURE.
>> YOU KNOW, THERE'S A PUBLIC
HEALTH SPECIALIST AT HARVARD
WHO'S WRITTEN A BOOK ON GUN
VIOLENCE AND HE SAYS CHILDREN
AGES 5 TO 14 IN THIS COUNTRY, 13
TIMES LIKELY -- AS LIKELY TO BE
MURDERED WITH GUNS THAN CHILDREN
IN OTHER INDUSTRIALIZED
COUNTRIES.
BUT MOST OF THESE DEATHS, THESE
KILLINGS, TAKE PLACE IN
NEIGHBORHOODS, IN HOMES.
IT'S NOT IN THE SCHOOLS.
SO ARE YOU REALLY DIRECTING YOUR
SOLUTION, YOUR PROPOSED
SOLUTION, TO THE RIGHT PLACE?
>> WELL, THIS ISN'T ABOUT A GUN
BAN.
THERE'S OVER 250 MILLION GUNS
ALREADY IN CIRCULATION IN THE
USA.
THAT BELL HAS ALREADY BEEN RUNG.
WE'RE FOCUSING ON WHATS
OCCASIONALLY IN OUR SCHOOLS.
AND WHAT CAN BE DONE TO PROTECT
OUR CHILDREN AND THEIR EDUCATORS
IN THE EVENT THAT THIS HAPPENS
AGAIN, WHICH IS INEVITABLE.
WE CANNOT CONTINUE TO HAVE THE
ONLY ARMED PERSON ON THE
PREMISES OF THE SCHOOL BE THE
MASS KILLER.
AND WE CAN'T AFFORD TO PUT
POLICE IN EVERY CAMPUS.
THERE'S A ONE IN A MILLION
CHANCE THIS IS GOING TO HAPPEN,
BUT IF WE HAVE VOLUNTEERS WHO
ARE TRAINED AND PREPARED TO
RESPOND WITH LETHAL FORCE, THEN
WE CAN LESSEN THE NUMBER OF
CASUALTIES THAT WILL OCCUR IN
THE FUTURE.
>> WHO WOULD BE RESPONSIBLE FOR
THIS TRAINING AND THIS VETTING
OF THESE ARMED PEOPLE IN THE
SCHOOLS?
WHO DO YOU PROPOSE WOULD DO
THAT?
>> WELL, I THINK LOCAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT.
I MEAN, PRESENTLY WHEN SOMETHING
HAPPENS LIKE THIS, WE CALL 911,
AND THERE'S A FIVE TO TEN-MINUTE
DELAY BEFORE THE POLICE ARRIVE.
SECONDS COUNT.
WHEN THERE'S THAT KIND OF DELAY.
AND SO THE POLICE CAN HELP
PROVIDE THE TRAINING, THE
UPDATED TRAINING.
WE NEED REGULAR REVIEW AND
PRACTICE SO THAT WHOEVER IS
VOLUNTEERING AS THE CAMPUS
RESPONDER, AND THIS IS NOT A
MANDATORY THING, BUT WHOEVER
DOES THAT IS AS PREPARED AS
POSSIBLE.
AND NO ONE CAN BE FULLY PREPARED
FOR THE STRESS THAT OCCURS IN
SUCH A SITUATION AS BEING
CONFRONTED WITH A KILLER.
>> I'M CURIOUS, HAVE YOU GOTTEN
MUCH SUPPORT FOR THIS IDEA, FOR
THIS NOTION?
ARE THERE PEOPLE WHO FEEL LIKE
THIS IS A GOOD IDEA WHO ARE
BACKING YOU?
>> OH, THERE'S MANY PEOPLE.
I WAS CALLED BY ONE TEACHER IN
SOUTHERN OREGON ON SATURDAY
MORNING.
AND HE SAID, I WANT YOU TO KNOW,
I'VE BEEN CARRYING A PISTOL FOR
YEARS ON CAMPUS.
I KNOW OF A PRINCIPAL WHO'S
RECENTLY RETIRED WHO ALSO
CARRIED -- CONCEALED CARRIED FOR
YEARS BECAUSE HE WASN'T GOING TO
LET WHAT HAPPENED IN COLUMBINE
HAPPEN IN HIS SCHOOL.
THERE'S MANY PEOPLE WHO SAY A
PASSIVE APPROACH ONLY GIVES
POWER TO A PSYCHOPATH.
AND IT'S NOT A FEDERAL ISSUE.
THIS CAN BE RESOLVED BY SCHOOL
DISTRICTS.
IT'S BEING RESOLVED RIGHT NOW IN
HAROLD SCHOOL DISTRICT IN TEXAS
WHERE THEY'VE RESEARCHED IT AND
SAID WE'RE GOING TO ALLOW
CONCEALED CARRY PERMIT HOLERS
WHO ARE TEACHERS AND OTHER STAFF
TO BE ABLE TO CARRY IN OUR
SCHOOLS SO THAT WHAT HAPPENS IN
OTHER PLACES WILL NOT HAPPEN
HERE.
>> WE'VE GOT TO LEAVE IT THERE.
WE'RE RUNNING OUT OF TIME.
REPRESENTATIVE RICHARDSON, THANK
YOU VERY MUCH.
APPRECIATE YOUR PERSPECTIVE.
MORE OF OUR SPECIAL COVERAGE
AFTER A QUICK BREAK.
>> Reporter: THEY WERE JUST 6
YEARS OLD, THEIR LIVES CUT SHORT
BY A HORRIFIC ACT OF VIOLENCE.
TODAY FAMILIES FACED WHAT SEEMS
TO BE UNBEARABLE AS THEY SAY
GOOD-BYE TO TWO FIRST GRADERS
KILLED IN THE SHOOTING AT THEIR
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
FUNERALS ARE BEING HELD THIS
HOUR FOR JACK PINTO AND NOAH
POZNER.
JACK LOVED SPORTS.
HE LOVED BASEBALL, WRESTLING,
FOOTBALL WAS HIS FAVORITE.
NOAH LOVED PLAYING WITH HIS
SIBLINGS, ESPECIALLY HIS TWIN
SISTER.
JACK AND NOAH ARE TWO OF THE 20
CHILDREN WHO DIED.
AT LAST NIGHT'S PRAYER SERVICE
HERE, THE PRESIDENT CALLED EACH
ONE BY NAME.
>> LET THE LITTLE CHILDREN COME
TO ME, JESUS SAID, AND DO NOT
HINDER THEM FOR TO SUCH BELONGS
THE KINGDOM OF HEAVEN.
CHARLOTTE, DANIEL, OLIVIA,
JOSEPHINE, ANA, DYLAN,
MADELEINE, CATHERINE, CHASE,
JESSE, JAMES, GRACE, EMILIE,
JACK, NOAH, CAROLINE, JESSICA,
BENJAMIN, AVIELLE, ALLISON.
GOD HAS CALLED THEM ALL HOME.
FOR THOSE OF US WHO REMAIN, LET
US FIND THE STRENGTH TO CARRY ON
AND MAKE OUR COUNTRY WORTHY OF
THEIR MEMORY.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS DECEMBER, REMEMBER --
YOU CAN STAY IN
AND SHARE SOMETHING...
OR YOU CAN GET OUT THERE
AND ACTUALLY SHARE SOMETHING.
♪
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OUR TENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
>>> THE MASSACRE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HAS REIGNITED
THE RAGING DEBATE OVER GUNS.
THE WEAPON USED TO MURDER THOSE
20 LITTLE CHILDREN AND 6 ADULTS,
HERE IS WHAT IT LOOKED LIKE, A
SEMI-AUTOMATIC BUSHMASTER .223
CALIBER ASSAULT RIFLE.
PEOPLE ARE ANGRY, SOME PEOPLE,
THIS COMBAT-STYLE WEAPON IS NOT
ILLEGAL BUT IS PROTECTED UNDER
THE CONSTITUTION.
I WANT TO BRING IN JOHN.
FEDERAL GUN LAWS WHAT IS THE
GENERAL IDEA HERE?
>> LOOK, FIRST OF ALL, YOUR
PRODUCER ASKED US TO LOOK INTO
GUN LAWS.
WE THOUGHT THIS WOULD BE A
STRAIGHTFORWARD ASSIGNMENT TO
EXPLAIN THE LAWS, TURNED OUT TO
BE MORE COMPLICATED, MORE
CONVOLUTED THAN YOU COULD EVER
IMAGINE.
WE TRIED TO BOIL IT DOWN TO ITS
MOST BASIC PARTS.
LET'S FIRST TALK ABOUT THE
FEDERAL GUN LAWS.
FIRST OF ALL, WE KNOW THAT YOU
HAVE TO BE 21 IN ORDER TO
PURCHASE A HANDGUN FROM A
LICENSED DEALER.
LICENSED DEALER IS THE KEY HERE.
ALSO, 18 TO PURCHASE A LONG GUN,
A RIFLE, FROM A LICENSED DEALER.
BUT THAT'S REALLY WHERE IT
STOPS.
>> TELL US ABOUT THE FEDERAL
RESTRICTIONS.
>> THERE ARE SEVERAL FEDERAL
RESTRICTIONS, IF THE PERSON
KNOWS THAT YOU FIT WITHIN THIS
CRITERIA.
AGAIN, SO THERE ARE NO
RESTRICTIONS ON PRIVATE SALES OF
ANY PERSON CAN SELL A GUN TO
ANOTHER PERSON UNDER FEDERAL
LAW.
THERE ARE NO RESTRICTIONS UNDER
SALES AT GUN SHOWS, BUT IF A
SELLER KNOWS THAT A PERSON FITS
WITHIN ANY OF THIS, I'LL LIST
IT, IF WE HAVE THIS GRAPHIC TO
SHOW, IF YOU ARE A CONVICTED
FELON, A FUGITIVE OF JUSTICE, AN
UNLAWFUL USER OR ADDICTED TO
CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES,
ADJUDICATED AS A MENTAL
DEFECTIVE OR COMMITTED TO A
MENTAL INSTITUTION, IF YOU'RE AN
ILLEGAL ALIEN OR UNLAWFULLY
LIVING IN THE U.S., IF YOU'RE AN
ALIEN ADMITTED TO THE U.S. ON A
NONIMMIGRANT VISA, IF YOU'RE
DISHONORABLY DISCHARGED FROM THE
ARMED SERVICES, A CITIZEN OF THE
U.S. BUT RENOUNCED CITIZENSHIP
IF YOU ARE UNDER PROTECTION
ORDER OR RESTRAINING ORDER DUE
TO DOMESTIC VIOLENCE OR
CONVICTED OF DOMESTIC VIOLENCE,
IT IS A LONG LIST, BUT IF YOU
FALL WITHIN ANY OF THOSE
CATEGORIES, THEN WHEN IT COMES
TO PRIVATE SALES, A PERSON
SHOULD NOT SELL TO YOU.
BUT IF THEY DON'T KNOW, THEY CAN
DO IT.
>> ALL RIGHT.
WE'LL BRING YOU BACK, GEORGE.
WE'RE RUNNING OUT OF TIME.
WE'LL BRING YOU BACK TO TALK
ABOUT THE STATES WITH THE
TOUGHEST RESTRICTIONS AND THOSE
MORE LENIENT BECAUSE IT IS VERY
DIFFERENT.
THANK YOU, GEORGE.
THE DEBATE OVER GUN CONTROL
LIKELY TO CONTINUE, OF COURSE,
IN THE WAKE OF THIS MASSACRE.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS DECEMBER, REMEMBER --
WHAT STARTS
WITH ADDING A FRIEND...
♪
...COULD END
WITH ADDING A CLOSE FRIEND.
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
>>> DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, THE
PRINCIPAL OF THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HERE IN
NEWTOWN IS BEING REMEMBERED AS A
HERO.
SHE WAS KILLED WHEN SHE
CONFRONTED THE GUNMAN IN HER
SCHOOL.
HER COLLEAGUE SAID SHE WAS A
GREAT EDUCATOR, WHOSE ENTHUSIASM
NEVER FLAGGED.
NOW HER HUSBAND GEORGE IS ALSO
TALKING ABOUT HIS WIFE, AND
THEIR LIFE TOGETHER.
THE TWO WERE MARRIED TEN YEARS
AGO AFTER MEETING WHEN THEY WERE
BOTH WORKING AT ANOTHER SCHOOL.
GARY TUCHMAN SPOKE WITH THE
FAMILY.
>> Reporter: WHILE DAWN WAS THE
PRINCIPAL AT SANDY HOOK, GEORGE
STILL TAUGHT AT THE MIDDLE
SCHOOL WHERE THEY MET.
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE DAY FRIDAY,
THIS IS HOW GEORGE FOUND OUT
WHAT HAPPENED.
>> ONE OF THE KIDS CAME UP WITH
A COMPUTER, AND SAID,
SOMETHING'S HAPPENING AT SANDY
HOOK SCHOOL, AND YOUR WIFE'S
BEEN KILLED.
>> Reporter: GEORGE RACED OUT OF
SCHOOL AND INTO A NIGHTMARE.
LIKE ALL THE FAMILIES OF VICTIMS
THEY WANT TO KNOW MORE.
ON THIS DAY, THEY HAVE LEARNED
MORE.
TWO TEACHERS SURVIVED TOLD
GEORGE THEY WERE HAVING A
MEETING WITH DAWN WHEN THE SHOTS
STARTED RINGING OUT.
>> DAWN PUT HERSELF IN JEOPARDY
AND I HAVE BEEN ANGRY ABOUT
THAT.
ANGRY UNTIL JUST NOW, TODAY,
WHEN I MET THE TWO WOMEN THAT
SHE TOLD TO GO INTO SHELTER
WHILE SHE ACTUALLY CONFRONTED
THE GUNMAN, SHE COULD HAVE
AVOIDED THAT.
AND SHE DIDN'T.
I KNEW SHE WOULDN'T.
SO I'M NOT ANGRY ANYMORE.
I'M NOT ANGRY.
I'M NOT ANGRY ANYMORE.
I'M JUST VERY SAD.
>> DAWN'S DAUGHTER CHRISTINA HAS
BEEN TWEETING ABOUT HER MOM.
SHE SAYS, MY MOM, DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG, WAS TAKEN TRAGICALLY
FROM ME.
BUT SHE WENT DOWN IN A BLAZE OF
GLORY THAT TRULY REPRESENTS WHO
SHE WAS.
SHE ALSO TWEETED OUT THIS
PICTURE OF PRESIDENT OBAMA,
HOLDING DAWN HOCHSPRUNG'S
GRANDDAUGHTER.
FOR MORE INFORMATION ON HOW YOU
CAN HELP THOSE AFFECTED, VISIT
CNN.COM/IMPACT.
is it really 100 calories?
Let me put you on webcan...
...lean roasted chicken...
and a creamy broth
Mmm
I can still see you.
[ Male announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
♪
BECOMING
PART OF THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
TREES WILL TALK TO NETWORKS
WILL TALK TO SCIENTISTS
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE.
CARS WILL TALK TO ROAD SENSORS
WILL TALK TO STOPLIGHTS
ABOUT TRAFFIC EFFICIENCY.
THE AMBULANCE WILL TALK
TO PATIENT RECORDS
WILL TALK TO DOCTORS
ABOUT SAVING LIVES.
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
THE NEXT BIG THING?
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
♪
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
♪
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.