♪
>> OH, GOD EXALTED IN FULL OF
COMPASSION, GRANT PERFECT PEACE
IN YOUR SHELTERING PRESENCE
AMONG THE HOLY AND THE PURE TO
THE SOULS OF ALL OF OUR LOVED
ONES THAT PERISHED IN THAT
HORRIBLE DAY.
THEY HAVE GONE TO THEIR ETERNAL
HOME, MASTER OF MERCY, WE
BESEECH YOU.
REMEMBER ALL OF THEIR WORTHY AND
RIGHTEOUS DEEDS THAT THEY
PERFORMED IN THE LAND OF THE
LIVING.
MAY THEIR SOULS BE BOUND UP IN
THE BOND OF LIFE ETERNAL.
THERE IS NO DEATH, JUST
TRANSFORMATION.
MAY THEY REST IN PEACE.
AND LET US SAY AMEN.
>> AMEN.
PLEASE, BE SEATED.
AND LET US UNITE OUR HEARTS IN
PRAYER.
OH, GOD OF LOVE AND MERCY.
WE COME BEFORE YOU THIS NIGHT
WITH BROKEN HEARTS.
WE OFFER YOU OUR TEARS AND OUR
PAIN, OUR ANGER AND OUR SORROW.
OH, LORD, THERE WAS A HOLE SO
LARGE WE WONDER IF EVEN YOU AND
YOUR GREATNESS CAN FILL IT AS WE
GRIEVE AND MOURN FOR THOSE WHO
ARE LOST.
EACH LIGHT THAT SITS BEFORE US
IS A LIGHT THAT'S BEEN LOST TO
OUR WORLD.
SO MANY INNOCENTS, SO MANY
BRAVE, LORD, ALL WE CAN DO IS
THROW OURSELVES UPON YOUR TENDER
MERCIES, TRUSTING THAT YOU HEAR
OUR PRAYERS.
WE KNOW THOSE WHO ARE LOST,
BECAUSE THEY ARE OURS, LORD.
NOT NAMES ON SOME LIST, BUT OUR
MOTHERS OR SISTERS, OUR BROTHERS
OR FRIENDS, KINDRED ALL, BECAUSE
IF WE DID NOT KNOW THEM
OURSELVES, WE KNOW SOMEONE WHO
DID.
AND SO WE PRAY, LORD, FOR ALL
THE SOULS LOST AND ALL THE
FAMILIES AND FRIENDS WHO ARE SO
TORN BY GRIEF.
FOR IN THIS MOMENT, WE ARE ALL
YOUR CHILDREN, A FAMILY RELATED
BY YOUR LOVE.
SO HELP US TO CARE FOR THESE
FAMILIES IN THEIR SORROW AND FOR
EACH OTHER IN OURS.
MAY THEY FEEL THE HEALING
EMBRACE OF A NEIGHBORHOOD, A
TOWN, A STATE, A NATION, A
WORLD.
HELP US TO FOREVER REMEMBER THAT
WE EMBRACE THE GRIEVING AS OUR
OWN AND BRING US TOGETHER AS ONE
FAMILY TO LIVE TOGETHER IN PEACE
AND AMITY.
HELP US TO SHARE THE LIGHTS THAT
STAND BEFORE US.
HELP US TO CARRY THEM OUT INTO
THIS WORLD AND SHARE IT WITH A
WORLD SO IN SORROW AND SO IN
NEED.
FOR WE PRAY ALL OF THIS IN THE
NAME OF YOUR LOVE AS WE ALL SAY
AMEN.
>> WE INVITE YOU TO JOIN WITH US
IN PSALM 23 IN WHATEVER WAY YOU
KNOW IT IN YOUR HEART.
DOESN'T HAVE TO BE THE WORDS
WE'RE OFFERING HERE.
THE LORD IS MY SHEPHERD, I SHALL
NOT WANT.
HE MAKETH ME TO LIE DOWN IN
GREEN PASTURES.
HE LEAD ME BESIDE THE STILL
WATERS.
HE RESTORE MY SOUL.
HE LEAD ME IN THE PATH OF
RIGHTEOUSNESS FOR HIS NAME SAKE.
THOUGH I WALK THROUGH THE SHADOW
OF DEATH, I WILL FEAR NO EVIL,
FOR THOU AREN'T WITH ME BY ROD
AND BY STAFF THEY COMFORT ME.
THOU PREPARE US THE TABLE BEFORE
ME IN THE PRESENCE OF MY
ENEMIES, THOU ANOINT MY HEAD
WITH OIL, MY CUP RUNNETH OVER.
SURELY, GOODNESS AND MERCY THAT
FOLLOW ME ALL THE DAYS OF MY
LIFE, AND I WILL DWELL IN THE
HOUSE OF THE LORD FOREVER.
>> LET US PRAY.
GOD IN HEAVEN, WE THANK YOU FOR
YOUR PRESENCE WITH US HERE ON
EARTH.
WE KNOW THAT THE CHILDREN WHO
WERE LOST IN THIS TRAGEDY FIRST
BELONGED TO YOU BEFORE THEY
BELONGED TO US.
AND WE COMMIT THEIR SOULS TO
YOU, TO YOUR LOVING, ETERNAL
CARE.
WE THANK YOU, LORD, THAT THEY
ARE NOW IN A PLACE OF NO MORE
SICKNESS, NO MORE SADNESS, NO
MORE SUFFERING, AND NO MORE
SORROW, AS THERE IS FINALLY NO
MORE SIN IN THE PRESENCE OF YOU,
THEIR SAVIOR AND OURS.
DEAR LORD, AS WE LEAVE THE
CHILDREN THAT WE HAVE LOST IN
YOUR HANDS, WE ASK THAT BY YOUR
GRACE, YOU WOULD EMPOWER US TO
BLESS AND COMFORT THE CHILDREN
WHO ARE STILL HERE IN OUR HANDS.
PLEASE BE WITH THEM IN A SPECIAL
WAY AS THEY GRIEVE THE LOSS OF
SIBLINGS AND FRIENDS.
LIFE WILL NEVER BE THE SAME FOR
THEM.
WE ASK THAT YOU WOULD HELP THESE
PRECIOUS LITTLE ONES TO CARRY
THE SPIRITS OF THEIR LOST LOVED
ONES IN THEIR HEARTS AS THEY GO
ALONG LIVING THEIR LIVES TO ITS
FULLEST, ACCORDING TO YOUR WILL
FOR EACH OF THESE GIRLS AND
BOYS.
AND LORD, WE ASK MOST OF ALL
THAT YOU WOULD USE US TO BE A
SOURCE OF YOUR HEALING IN THE
MIDST OF THEIR WOUNDS.
THAT YOU WOULD USE THOSE OF US
WHOSE CHILDREN ARE CRYING FOR
HOPE AS A SOURCE OF YOUR HOPE IN
THE MIDST OF ANY HOPELESSNESS,
AS YOU ARE THE GOD OF HOPE.
USE US TO REPLACE THEIR ANXIETY
WITH YOUR PEACE, AS YOU ARE THE
GOD OF PEACE.
AND PLEASE, FILL THEIR HEARTS
WITH THE SENSE OF YOUR LOVE,
YOUR PRESENCE, YOUR POWER, AND
MOST OF ALL, A SENSE OF YOUR
CARE.
NOT KNOWING WHAT THE FUTURE
HOLDS, BUT KNOWING THAT YOU HOLD
IT, AS YOU HOLD THESE PRECIOUS
LITTLE ONES WHO ARE STILL WITH
US TODAY IN YOUR HANDS THROUGH
OUR HANDS.
AND LORD, WE ASK THIS ALL IN THE
NAME OF THE ONE WHO SAID, UNLESS
WE BECOME LIKE LITTLE CHILDREN,
WE CANNOT ENTER THE KINGDOM OF
GOD.
MAKE US ALL CHILDLIKE AND NOT
CHILDISH.
AND OUR THOUGHTS AND OUR WORDS
AND OUR ATTITUDES AND ACTIONS
AND BEHAVIORS NOT ONLY BEFORE
OTHERS, BUT BEFORE YOU, THAT WE
MAY LOOK TO YOU FOR BETTER DAYS
AHEAD AND THAT WE MAY FULFILL
YOUR PURPOSE FOR US ON THIS
EARTH.
FOR WE PRAY ALL OF THIS IN THE
NAME OF OUR PRECIOUS LORD AND
SAVIOR, JESUS.
AMEN.
♪
>> IN THE NAME OF GOD, THE
COMPASSIONATE AND THE MERCIFUL,
THE MUSLIM COMMUNITY AT THE AL
HEDAYA MUSLIM CENTER IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AND THROUGHOUT THE
NATION, JOINS WITH OUR FELLOW
AMERICANS, DEALING WITH THOSE
WHO DIED IN THE SENSELESS
TRAGEDY AND PRAYING FOR THEM AND
THEIR FAMILIES.
WE ASK GOD TO ASK THOSE LOST A
SPECIAL PLACE IN PARADISE, AND
WE ASK THEIR FAMILIES TO BE
GRANTED THE STRENGTH TO ENDURE
THE UNENDURABLE.
IT IS IN SUCH TIMES OF ALMOST
UNBEARABLE LOSS THAT WE SEEK THE
COMFORT WITH OUR CREATOR AND
THAT ARTIFICIAL DIVISIONS OF
FAITH FALL AWAY TO REVEAL A
NATION OF MOTHERS AND FATHERS,
BROTHERS AND SISTERS, SONS AND
DAUGHTERS ALL UNITED IN A DESIRE
TO BRING HEALING AND RENEWED
HOPE.
THE KORAN, ISLAM'S REVEALED
TEXT, TELLS US THAT GOD'S MERCY
AND COMPASSION ARE WITHOUT LIMIT
AND ALWAYS AVAILABLE FOR THOSE
WHO ASK.
GOD SAYS, WHEN MY SERVANTS
QUESTION YOU ABOUT ME, TELL THEM
THAT I AM NEAR.
I ANSWER THE PRAYER OF EVERY
PERSON WHO CALLS ON ME.
CHAPTER 2 VERSE 186, THE
KORAN -- IN THE KORAN, GOD ALSO
SAYS, GIVE GLAD TIDINGS TO THOSE
WHO ENDURE WITH PATIENCE, WHO
WHEN AFFLICTED WITH CALAMITY
SAY, WE BELONG TO GOD AND TO HIM
WE SHALL RETURN.
SUCH ARE THE PEOPLE ON WHOM
THERE ARE BLESSINGS AND MERCY
FROM GOD.
CHAPTER 2, VERSE 155 TO 157.
SO LET US ALL, OF EVERY FAITH,
OF EVERY BACKGROUND, PRAY FOR
GOD'S COMFORT AT THIS TIME OF
HEARTBREAKING TRAGEDY.
BARELY, WITH EVERY DIFFICULT,
THERE IS EASY.
BARELY, WITH EVERY DIFFICULTY,
THERE IS EASE, CHAPTER 94, VERSE
5 THROUGH 6.
AMEN.
>> A PRAYER FOR THE FIRST
RESPONDERS.
LET US PRAY.
HOLY GOD, MANY OF THESE MEN AND
WOMEN YOU CALLED INTO SERVICE
WHEN THEY WERE JUST CHILDREN.
THEY WANTED TO BE POLICE
OFFICERS AND FIREFIGHTERS AND
CARE FOR THOSE THAT WERE IN
NEED, LORD.
YOU GAVE THEM GIFTS FOR THEIR
LIFE TO SERVE.
YOU ASKED THEM TO PAY A HIGH
PRICE FOR ALL THE SKILLS THAT
THEY HAVE BEEN GIVEN, FOR THE
STRENGTH THAT THEY HAVE.
YOU EQUIPPED THEM.
YOU GAVE THEM A WILLINGNESS TO
LEARN, TO TRAIN, TO STUDY.
SERVE IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT
WHEN A CALL WOULD COME IN.
AND YOU GAVE THEM THE
WILLINGNESS TO RESPOND WHEN THIS
TOWN NEEDED THEM THE MOST.
LORD, WE THANK YOU FOR THOSE IN
THIS TOWN THAT RESPONDED, BUT WE
THANK YOU ALSO FOR THOSE
THROUGHOUT THE STATE THAT CAME
WHEN THE NEED WAS GIVEN.
WE THANK YOU, LORD, FOR THEIR
GIFTS AND THEIR STRENGTH AND
THEIR COURAGE.
SO WE ASK YOU, LORD, TO WALK
WITH THEM IN THE DAYS AHEAD, TO
SURROUND THEM WITH YOUR ANGELS,
TO GIVE THEM PEOPLE WHO WILL
LISTEN TO THEIR STORY, TO LISTEN
TO WHAT THEY SAW THAT WAS NOT
FOR ANYONE TO EVER SEE.
LORD, WE PLACE EACH AND EVERY
ONE OF THESE MEN AND WOMEN IN
YOUR CARE, BUT WE WILL BE
FAITHFUL TO THEM.
WE WILL CARE FOR THEM.
WE WILL CONTINUE TO EQUIP THEM,
AND WE WILL KEEP THEM EVER IN
OUR PRAYERS.
AMEN.
>> FOR THE MOTHERS AND THE
FATHERS AND THE BROTHERS AND
SISTERS, THE GRANDPARENTS.
FOR ALL OF YOU TODAY.
THIS IS A SACRED TEXT FROM THE
BAHA'I FAITH.
IT WAS WRITTEN AS A LETTER TO A
MOTHER WHO WAS MOURNING THE LOSS
OF HER CHILD.
I'VE ADAPTED IT FOR THIS
EVENING.
ALTHOUGH THE LOSS OF A CHILD IS
INDEED HEARTBREAKING AND BEYOND
THE LIMITS OF HUMAN ENDURANCE,
YET ONE WHO KNOWETH AND
UNDERSTANDETH IS ASSURED THAT
THE CHILD HAD NOT BEEN LOST, BUT
RATHER HAVE STEPPED FROM THIS
WORLD INTO ANOTHER, AND YOU WILL
FIND THEM IN THE DEVINE REALM.
THAT REUNION SHALL BE FOR
ETERNITY, WHILE IN THIS WORLD,
SEPARATION IS INEVITABLE AND
BRINGETH WITH IT A BURNING
GRIEF.
PRAISE BE UNTO GOD THAT THOU HAS
FAITH.
TURNING THY FAITH TO THE
EVERLASTING KINGDOM AND BELIEVE
IN THE EVERLASTING WORLD.
BE NOT DISCONSULATE.
DO NOT LANGUISH.
DO NOT SIGH.
NEITHER WAIL, NOR WEEP, FOR
AGITATION AND MOURNING DEEPLY
EFFECT THE SOUL, THEIR SOUL, IN
THE DEVINE REALM.
>> THAT BELOVED CHILD ADDRESS
FROM THE HIDDEN WORLD.
OH, THOU KIND MOTHER AND FATHER,
THANK DEVINE PROVIDENCE THAT I
HAVE BEEN FREED FROM A SMALL AND
GLOOMY CAGE, AND LIKE THE BIRDS
OF THE MEADOWS, HAVE SOARED TO
THE DEVINE WORLD, A WORLD WHICH
IS SPACIOUS, ILLUMINED AND EVER
JOYOUS AND JUBILANT.
THEREFORE, LAMENT NOT, OH,
MOTHER AND FATHER, AND BE NOT
GRIEVED.
I AM NOT OF THE LOST, NOR HAVE I
BEEN OBLITERATED AND DESTROYED.
I HAVE SHAKEN OFF THE MORTAL
FORM AND HAVE RAISED MY BANNER
IN THIS SPIRITUAL WORLD.
FOLLOWING THIS SEPARATION IS
EVERLASTING COMPANIONSHIP.
THOU SHALT FIND ME IN THE HEAVEN
OF THE LORD, IMMERSED IN AN
OCEAN OF LIGHT.
>> GOD, WE CALL YOU BY MANY
NAMES.
MODERN EYE, GREAT SPIRIT, HIGHER
POWER, DEVINE ONE, BUT HOWEVER
WE ADDRESS YOU, YOU ARE ALWAYS
FATHER AND MOTHER TO US ALL, AND
WE ARE YOUR CHILDREN.
WE ARE YOUR FAMILY.
WE ASK YOUR BLESSING, LORD, UPON
THE COUNSELORS AND THE CLERGY
AND ALL THE CAREGIVERS AMONG US.
THEY HAVE GREAT PASSION FOR WHAT
THEY DO AND WHEN EVERYONE DOES
THEIR PASSION, WE ARRIVE AT
COMPASSION, AND WE THANK YOU.
WE KNOW THAT YOU'RE MOST AWARE
OF THEIR NEEDS.
THEY, TOO, BECOME TIRED AND
SOMETIMES CLOSE TO BURNING OUT.
HOW MUCH WE NEED ONE ANOTHER.
WHEN YOU CALL JEREMIAH OR AMOS
OR BARUK AND ALL YOUR PRECIOUS
APOSTLES AND PROPHETS, THEY
HEDGED AT FIRST.
BUT EACH TIME, IN TURN, THEY
GAVE THEIR YES AND THEY FOLLOWED
YOU.
KNOWING THAT YOU WERE ALWAYS
AMONG THEM, ALWAYS SUPPORTING
THEM.
THEY WERE CONDUITS FOR YOUR EYES
AND YOUR EARS AND YOUR VOICE AND
YOUR HANDS.
THEY WERE THE CLAY KNOWING THAT
YOU ALWAYS WERE THE POTTER, AND
THEY WERE REZSILIENT IN YOUR
HANDS.
WHEN JESUS FELT THE NEED TO GET
AWAY FOR SOME RESPITE HIMSELF,
HE WENT TO THE MOUNTAINS OR INTO
THE WILDERNESS OR OUT TO THE
SEASHORE, AND THE GREAT NUMBERS
OF PEOPLE IN NEED ALWAYS
FOLLOWED.
TIRED AND DRAINED AS HE WAS, HE
LOOKED ON THEM WITH COMPASSION.
ANOINT ALL YOUR PEOPLE, LORD,
ALL THOSE WHO MINISTER TO YOU AS
THEY MINISTER TO ONE ANOTHER AND
ESPECIALLY THIS WEEK AS THEY
MINISTER TO THE BODY, MIND, AND
SPIRIT, TO THE WHOLE COMMUNITY
OF SANDY HOOK AND NEWTOWN.
A MODEL FOR THE NATION, A MODEL
FOR THE WORLD, AND WE THANK YOU
FOR THE WORLD'S SUPPORT,
CALLING, E-MAILING, TEXTING
THEIR LOVE AND THEIR COMMITMENT
TO BE ONE WITH US.
USE THEM, LORD.
TAKE THE PASSION THAT EACH ONE
HAS AND TRANSFORM IT TOTALLY,
COMPLETELY INTO YOUR SPIRIT OF
COMPASSION.
AND WE ASK THIS ALL, AMEN.
AMEN.
>> NEWTOWN IS A PLACE THAT LOVES
CHILDREN ABOVE ALL.
FAMILIES MOVE TO NEWTOWN BECAUSE
WE ARE A CARING AND LOVING
COMMUNITY.
WE ARE ALSO A PLACE THAT HAS
GREAT PRIDE IN OUR SCHOOLS,
PRIDE THAT PROPELS THE STUDENTS
IN THOSE SCHOOLS WITH THEIR
OUTSTANDING TEACHERS AND
ADMINISTRATORS TO HIGH
ACHIEVEMENT AND GREAT PERSONAL
WORTH.
THE HORROR THAT WAS VISITED UPON
OUR SANDY HOOK SCHOOL WAS NOT
DESERVED.
IT WAS AN ANGRY AND DESPERATE
ACT OF A CONFUSED YOUNG MAN.
THERE'S NO BLAME TO BE LAID ON
US, BUT THERE IS A GREAT BURDEN
AND A GREAT CHALLENGE THAT THESE
FAMILIES DEVASTATED BY
UNSPEAKABLE HARM KNOW AND TRUST
THAT WE LOVE THEM AND WILL DO
EVERYTHING WE CAN TO HELP THEM
HEAL.
I KNOW THAT NEWTOWN WILL
PREVAIL, THAT WE WILL NOT FALL
TO ACTS OF VIOLENCE.
IT IS A DEFINING MOMENT FOR OUR
TOWN, BUT IT DOES NOT DEFINE US.
WE ARE NEWTOWN, A SPECIAL AND
CARING PLACE.
WE ARE DEFINED BY ACTS OF
COURAGE, BY ACTS OF LOVE, AND BY
OUR CONTINUING COMMITMENT AND
LOVE FOR OUR CHILDREN AND
FAMILIES.
IT IS MY PLEASURE, LADIES AND
GENTLEMEN, TO PRESENT TO YOU
GOVERNOR DAN MALLOY.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> PAT, THANK YOU FOR ALL OF THE
GREAT WORK THAT YOU HAVE DONE
FOR THIS COMMUNITY IN THE LAST
THREE DAYS, TO THE POLICE CHIEF,
AND TO THE SUPERINTENDENT OF
SCHOOLS, THANK YOU FOR YOUR
GREAT SERVICE, AS WELL AS TO ALL
OF THE FIRST RESPONDERS.
THANK YOU.
WHEN I CAME IN TO THE HALL, ONE
OF THE FIRST SONGS TO BE PLAYED
ON THE PIANO WAS "AMAZING
GRACE," WHICH IS FITTING FOR ANY
NUMBER OF REASONS.
IT'S BECOME AN ANTHEM FOR FIRST
RESPONDERS, IT HAS GREAT WORDS,
IT ALSO SPEAKS OF THE POWER OF
FAITH.
"AMAZING GRACE" WAS WRITTEN BY A
FORMER SEA CAPTAIN ENGAGED IN
THE SLAVE TRADE.
AND THOSE PROFOUND WORDS THAT "I
ONCE WAS LOST BUT NOW AM FOUND"
SPEAK TO US ON A DAY LIKE TODAY.
WHEN WE ARE CALLED UPON, DARE I
SAY REQUIRED TO BE INVESTED IN
OUR FAITH, A FAITH SO EVIDENT IN
THIS ROOM AND IN THIS COMMUNITY
AT THIS TIME.
A FAITH THAT IS, AFTER ALL, AT
ITS VERY CORE, A GIFT FROM GOD.
A FAITH IN WHICH WE FIND COMFORT
AND HOPE AND COMPASSION.
A FAITH IN WHICH WE ARE GIVEN
THE POWER TO GO ON.
TO SURVIVE THAT WHICH HAS
BEFALLEN THIS COMMUNITY, THESE
FAMILIES, THESE SPOUSES, THAT
WHICH HAS HAPPENED AND IS
UNIMAGINABLE AND UNTHINKABLE AND
WAS NEVER, WE THOUGHT, INTENDED
TO BE VISITED UPON US HERE IN
CONNECTICUT OR IN NEWTOWN OR IN
SANDY HOOK.
I CHOOSE TO THINK ABOUT THE FACT
THAT IN THE COMING DAYS WE WILL
OFFICIALLY ENTER WINTER.
AND THAT IS ALWAYS TO BE
FOLLOWED BY THE SPRING.
LET ME ASSURE YOU THAT IN
WINTER, EACH TIME I SEE THE
BEGINNING OF A SNOWFALL, I WILL
BE THINKING OF THOSE 27 SOULS
LOST JUST A FEW DAYS AGO.
EACH TIME THE DAY GETS A LITTLE
LONGER, I WILL THINK AND DREAM
OF THE LIVES THAT MIGHT HAVE
BEEN AND THE LIVES THAT WERE SO
FULL OF GRACE.
AND WHEN THE FLOWERS START TO
COME OUT OF THE GROUND, AND WHEN
THEY RISE UP, I WILL KNOW THAT
WE ARE IN TOUCH WITH THOSE THAT
WE HAVE LOST IN THE LAST FEW
DAYS.
WE WILL GO ON.
WE WILL FIND STRENGTH.
FAITH IS A GIFT, AS IS OUR
ABILITY TO SUPPORT ONE ANOTHER
IN OUR GREATER COMMUNITY.
TO ALL OF YOU, I EXTEND MY MOST
PROFOUND CONDOLENCES ON BEHALF
OF ALL OF YOUR FELLOW CITIZENS
FOR WHAT YOU HAVE SEEN, WT YOU
HAVE WITNESSED, AND WHAT YOU
HAVE PERSONALLY EXPERIENCED.
WE WILL MOVE ON, WE WILL NEVER
FORGET, WE WILL IN MANY WAYS BE
MADE STRONGER FOR WHAT HAS
TRANSPIRED, AND WE WILL GET
BETTER.
WE ARE BLESSED TODAY TO HAVE
WITH US THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES, WHO UPON MEETING
WITH PAT AND I JUST A LITTLE
WHILE AGO, SAID THAT THE MOST
DIFFICULT DAY OF HIS PRESIDENCY
WAS FRIDAY WHEN HE HEARD THE
NEWS OF THAT WHICH HAD BEFALLEN
THIS COMMUNITY.
I ASSURED HIM THAT CONNECTICUT,
NEWTOWN, AND SANDY HOOK ARE
STRONG, AND I WELCOMED HIM ON
YOUR BEHALF TO OUR COMMUNITY.
I NOW INTRODUCE THE PRESIDENT OF
THE UNITED STATES.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU, GOVERNOR.
TO ALL THE FAMILIES, FIRST
RESPONDERS, TO THE COMMUNITY OF
NEWTOWN, CLERGY, GUESTS,
SCRIPTURE TELLS US DO NOT LOSE
HEART.
THOUGH OUTWARDLY WE ARE WASTING
AWAY, INWARDLY, WE ARE BEING
RENEWED DAY BY DAY.
FOR LIGHT AND MOMENTARY TROUBLES
ARE ACHIEVING FOR US AN ETERNAL
GLORY THAT FAR OUTWEIGHS THEM
ALL, SO WE FIX OUR EYES NOT ON
WHAT IS SEEN, BUT ON WHAT IS
UNSEEN.
SINCE WHAT IS SEEN IS TEMPORARY,
BUT WHAT IS UNSEEN IS ETERNAL.
FOR WE KNOW THAT IF THE EARTHLY
TENT WE LIVE IN IS DESTROYED, WE
HAVE A BUILDING FROM GOD, AN
ETERNAL HOUSE IN HEAVEN NOT
BUILT BY HUMAN HANDS.
WE GATHER HERE IN MEMORY OF 20
BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN AND SIX
REMARKABLE ADULTS.
THEY LOST THEIR LIVES IN A
SCHOOL THAT COULD HAVE BEEN ANY
SCHOOL IN A QUIET TOWN FULL OF
GOOD AND DECENT PEOPLE THAT
COULD BE ANY TOWN IN AMERICA.
HERE IN NEWTOWN, I COME TO OFFER
THE LOVE AND PRAYERS OF A
NATION.
I AM VERY MINDFUL THAT MERE
WORDS CANNOT MATCH THE DEPTHS OF
YOUR SORROW, NOR CAN THEY HEAL
YOUR WOUNDED HEARTS.
I CAN ONLY HOPE IT HELPS FOR YOU
TO KNOW THAT YOU'RE NOT ALONE IN
YOUR GRIEF.
THAT OUR WORLD, TOO, HAS BEEN
TORN APART.
THAT ALL ACROSS THIS LAND OF
OURS, WE HAVE WEPT WITH YOU.
WE'VE PULLED OUR CHILDREN TIGHT,
AND YOU MUST KNOW THAT WHATEVER
MEASURE OF COMFORT WE CAN
PROVIDE, WE WILL PROVIDE.
WHATEVER PORTION OF SADNESS THAT
WE CAN SHARE WITH YOU TO EASE
THIS HEAVY LOAD, WE WILL GLADLY
BEAR IT.
NEWTOWN, YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
AS THESE DIFFICULT DAYS HAVE
UNFOLDED, YOU'VE ALSO INSPIRED
US.
WITH STORIES OF STRENGTH AND
RESOLVE AND SACRIFICE.
WE KNOW THAT WHEN DANGER ARRIVED
IN THE HALLS OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY, THE SCHOOL'S STAFF
DID NOT FLINCH.
THEY DID NOT HESITATE.
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG AND MARY
SHERLACH, VICKI SOTO, LAUREN
RUSSEAU, RACHEL DAVINO, AND ANN
MARIE MURPHY, THEY ALL RESPONDED
IN HOW WE HOPE WE ALL WOULD
RESPOND IN SUCH TERRIFYING
CIRCUMSTANCES, WITH COURAGE AND
WITH LOVE, GIVING THEIR LIVES TO
PROTECT THE CHILDREN IN THEIR
CARE.
WE KNOW THAT THERE WERE OTHER
TEACHERS WHO BARRICADED
THEMSELVES INSIDE CLASSROOMS AND
KEPT STEADY THROUGH IT ALL AND
REASSURED THEIR STUDENTS BY
SAYING WAIT FOR THE GOOD GUYS,
THEY ARE COMING.
SHOW ME YOUR SMILE.
AND WE KNOW THAT GOOD GUYS CAME,
THE FIRST RESPONDERS WHO RACED
TO THE SCENE HELPING TO GUIDE
THOSE IN HARM'S WAY TO SAFETY
AND COMFORT THOSE IN NEED,
HOLDING AT BAY THEIR OWN SHOCK
AND THEIR OWN TRAUMA, BECAUSE
THEY HAD A JOB TO DO AND OTHERS
NEEDED THEM MORE.
AND THEN THERE WERE THE SCENES
OF THE SCHOOL CHILDREN HELPING
ONE ANOTHER, HOLDING EACH OTHER,
DUTIFULLY FOLLOWING INSTRUCTIONS
IN THE WAY THAT YOUNG CHILDREN
SOMETIMES DO.
ONE CHILD EVEN TRYING TO
ENCOURAGE A GROWNUP BY SAYING,
"I KNOW KARATE, SO IT'S OKAY,
I'LL LEAD THE WAY OUT."
AS A COMMUNITY, YOU'VE INSPIRED
US, NEWTOWN.
IN THE FACE OF INDESCRIBABLE
VIOLENCE, IN THE FACE OF
UNCONSCIONABLE EVIL, YOU'VE
LOOKED OUT FOR EACH OTHER.
YOU'VE CARED FOR ONE ANOTHER.
AND YOU'VE LOVED ONE ANOTHER.
THIS IS HOW NEWTOWN WILL BE
REMEMBERED, AND WITH TIME AND
GOD'S GRACE, THAT LOVE WILL SEE
YOU THROUGH.
BUT WE AS A NATION, WE ARE LEFT
WITH SOME HARD QUESTIONS.
SOMEONE ONCE DESCRIBED THE JOY
AND ANXIETY OF PARENTHOOD AS THE
EQUIVALENT OF HAVING YOUR HEART
OUTSIDE OF YOUR BODY ALL THE
TI
TIME, WALKING AROUND.
WITH THEIR VERY FIRST CRY, THIS
MOST PRECIOUS, VITAL PART OF
OURSELVES, OUR CHILD.
SUDDENLY EXPOSED TO THE WORLD
THE POSSIBLE MISHAP OR MALICE,
AND EVERY PARENT KNOWS THERE'S
NOTHING WE WILL NOT DO TO SHIELD
OUR CHILDREN FROM HARM, AND YET
WE ALSO KNOW THAT WITH THAT
CHILD'S VERY FIRST STEP AND EACH
STEP AFTER THAT, THEY ARE
SEPARATING FROM US.
THAT WE WON'T -- THAT WE CAN'T
ALWAYS BE THERE FOR THEM.
THEY WILL SUFFER SICKNESS AND
SETBACKS AND BROKEN HEARTS AND
DISAPPOINTMENTS, AND WE LEARN
THAT OUR MOST IMPORTANT JOB IS
TO GIVE THEM WHAT THEY NEED TO
BECOME SELF RELIANT AND CAPABLE
AND RESILIENT, READY TO FACE THE
WORLD WITHOUT FEAR.
AND WE KNOW WE CAN'T DO THIS BY
OURSELVES.
IT COMES AS A SHOCK AT A CERTAIN
POINT WHERE YOU REALIZE NO
MATTER HOW MUCH YOU LOVE THESE
KIDS, YOU CAN'T DO IT BY
YOURSELF.
THAT THIS JOB OF KEEPING OUR
CHILDREN SAFE AND TEACHING THEM
WELL IS SOMETHING WE CAN ONLY DO
TOGETHER.
WITH THE HELP OF FRIENDS AND
NEIGHBORS, THE HELP OF A
COMMUNITY AND THE HELP OF A
NATION.
AND IN THAT WAY WE COME TO
REALIZE THAT WE BEAR
RESPONSIBILITY FOR EVERY CHILD,
BECAUSE WE'RE COUNTING ON
EVERYBODY ELSE TO HELP LOOK
AFTER OURS.
THAT WE'RE ALL PARENTS, THAT
THEY ARE ALL OUR CHILDREN.
THIS IS OUR FIRST TASK, CARING
FOR OUR CHILDREN.
OUR FIRST JOB.
IF WE DON'T GET THAT RIGHT, WE
DON'T GET ANYTHING RIGHT.
THAT'S HOW, AS A SOCIETY, WE
WILL BE JUDGED.
AND BY THAT MEASURE, CAN WE
TRULY SAY, AS A NATION, THAT
WE'RE MEETING OUR OBLIGATIONS?
CAN WE HONESTLY SAY THAT WE'RE
DOING ENOUGH TO KEEP OUR
CHILDREN, ALL OF THEM, SAFE FROM
HARM?
CAN WE CLAIM, AS A NATION, THAT
WE'RE ALL TOGETHER THERE,
LETTING THEM KNOW THEY ARE LOVED
AND TEACHING THEM TO LOVE IN
RETURN?
CAN WE SAY THAT WE'RE TRULY
DOING ENOUGH TO GIVE ALL THE
CHILDREN OF THIS COUNTRY THE
CHANCE THEY DESERVE TO LIVE OUR
THEIR LIVES IN HAPPINESS AND
WITH PURPOSE?
I'VE BEEN REFLECTING ON THIS THE
LAST FEW DAYS, AND IF WE'RE
HONEST WITH OURSELVES, THE
ANSWER'S NO.
WE'RE NOT DOING ENOUGH.
AND WE WILL HAVE TO CHANGE.
SINCE I'VE BEEN PRESIDENT, THIS
IS THE FOURTH TIME WE HAVE COME
TOGETHER TO COMFORT A GRIEVING
COMMUNITY TORN APART BY MASS
SHOOTINGS.
FOURTH TIME WE'VE HUGGED
SURVIVORS, THE FOURTH TIME WE'VE
CONSOLED THE FAMILYIES OF
VICTIMS, AND IN BETWEEN, THERE
HAVE BEEN AN ENDLESS SERIES OF
DEADLY SHOOTINGS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY, DAILY REPORTS OF
VICTIMS, MANY OF THEM CHILDREN,
IN SMALL TOWNS AND CITIES ALL
ACROSS AMERICA.
VICTIMS WHO MUCH OF THE TIME
THEIR ONLY FAULT WAS BEING AT
THE WRONG PLACE AT THE WRONG
TIME.
WE CAN'T TOLERATE THIS ANYMORE.
THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
AND TO END THEM, WE MUST CHANGE.
WE WILL BE TOLD THAT THE CAUSES
OF SUCH VIOLENCE ARE COMPLEXED,
AND THAT IS TRUE.
NO SINGLE LAW, NO SET OF LAWS
CAN ELIMINATE EVIL FROM THE
WORLD OR PREVENT EVERY SENSELESS
ACT OF VIOLENCE IN OUR SOCIETY,
BUT THAT CAN'T BE AN EXCUSE FOR
AN ACTION.
SURELY WE CAN DO BETTER THAN
THIS.
IF THERE'S EVEN ONE STEP WE CAN
TAKE TO SAVE ANOTHER CHILD OR
ANOTHER PARENT OR ANOTHER TOWN
FROM THE GRIEF THAT'S VISITED
TUCSON AND AURORA AND OAK CREEK
AND NEWTOWN AND COMMUNITIES FROM
COLUMBINE TO BLACKSBURG BEFORE
THAT, THEN SURELY WE HAVE AN
OBLIGATION TO TRY.
IN THE COMING WEEKS, I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS,
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT, TO MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS, TO PARENTS
AND EDUCATORS, IN AN EFFORT
AIMED AT PREVENTING MORE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS, BECAUSE
WHAT CHOICE DO WE HAVE?
WE CAN'T ACCEPT EVENTS LIKE THIS
AS ROUTINE.
ARE WE REALLY PREPARED TO SAY
THAT WE'RE POWERLESS IN THE FACE
OF SUCH CARNAGE?
THAT THE POLITICS ARE TOO HARD.
ARE WE PREPARED TO SAY THAT SUCH
VIOLENCE VISITED ON OUR CHILDREN
YEAR AFTER YEAR AFTER YEAR IS
SOMEHOW THE PRICE OF OUR
FREEDOM?
YOU KNOW, ALL THE WORLD'S
RELIGIONS, SO MANY OF THEM
REPRESENTED HERE TODAY, START
WITH A SIMPLE QUESTION.
WHY ARE WE HERE?
WHAT GIVES OUR LIFE MEANING?
WHAT GIVES OUR ACTS PURPOSE?
WE KNOW OUR TIME ON THIS EARTH
IS FLEETING.
WE KNOW THAT WE WILL EACH HAVE
OUR SHARE OF PLEASURE AND PAIN,
THAT EVEN AFTER WE CHASE AFTER
SOME EARTHLY GOAL, WHETHER IT'S
WEALTH OR POWER OR FAME OR JUST
SIMPLE COMFORT, WE WILL, IN SOME
FASHION, FALL SHORT OF WHAT WE
HAD HOPED.
WE KNOW THAT NO MATTER HOW GOOD
OUR INTENTIONS, WE'LL ALL
STUMBLE SOMETIMES IN SOME WAY.
WE'LL MAKE MISTAKES, WE'LL
EXPERIENCE HARDSHIPS, AND EVEN
WHEN WE'RE TRYING TO DO THE
RIGHT THING, WE KNOW THAT MUCH
OF OUR TIME WILL BE SPENT
GROPING THROUGH THE DARKNESS, SO
OFTEN UNABLE TO DISCERN GOD'S
HEAVENLY PLANS.
THERE'S ONLY ONE THING WE CAN BE
SURE OF, AND THAT IS THE LOVE
THAT WE HAVE.
FOR OUR CHILDREN, FOR OUR
FAMILIES, FOR EACH OTHER.
THE WARMTH OF A SMALL CHILD'S
EMBRACE, THAT IS TRUE.
THE MEMORIES WE HAVE OF THEM,
THE JOY THAT THEY BRING, THE
WONDER WE SEE THROUGH THEIR
EYES, THAT FIERCE AND BOUNDLESS
LOVE WE FEEL FOR THEM, A LOVE
THAT TAKES US OUT OF OURSELVES
AND BINDS US TO SOMETHING
LARGER.
WE KNOW THAT'S WHAT MATTERS.
WE KNOW WE'RE ALWAYS DOING RIGHT
WHEN WE'RE TAKING CARE OF THEM.
WHEN WE'RE TEACHING THEM WELL.
WHEN WE'RE SHOWING ACTS OF
KINDNESS.
WE DON'T GO WRONG WHEN WE DO
THAT.
THAT'S WHAT WE CAN BE SURE OF,
AND THAT'S WHAT YOU, THE PEOPLE
OF NEWTOWN, HAVE REMINDED US.
THAT'S HOW YOU'VE INSPIRED US.
YOU REMIND US WHAT MATTERS.
AND THAT'S WHAT SHOULD DRIVE US
FORWARD IN EVERYTHING WE DO FOR
AS LONG AS GOD SEES FIT TO KEEP
US ON THIS EARTH.
LET THE LITTLE CHILDREN COME TO
ME, JESUS SAID, AND DO NOT
HINDER THEM, FOR TO SUCH BELONGS
THE KINGDOM OF HEAVEN.
CHARLOTTE, DANIEL, OLIVIA,
JOSEPHINE, ANA, DYLAN,
MADELEINE, CATHERINE, CHASE,
JESSE, JAMES, GRACE, EMILIE,
JACK, NOAH, CAROLINE, JESSICA,
BENJAMIN, AVIELLE, ALLISON.
GOD HAS CALLED THEM ALL HOME.
FOR THOSE OF US WHO REMAIN, LET
US FIND THE STRENGTH TO CARRY ON
AND MAKE OUR COUNTRY WORTHY OF
THEIR MEMORY.
MAY GOD BLESS AND KEEP THOSE
WE'VE LOST IN HIS HEAVENLY
PLACE.
MAY HE GRACE THOSE WE STILL HAVE
WITH HIS HOLY COMFORT, AND MAY
HE BLESS AND WATCH OVER THIS
COMMUNITY AND THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> ON BEHALF OF THE NEWTOWN
CLERGY ASSOCIATION, WE ARE SO
GRATEFUL TO OUR PRESIDENT FOR
SPENDING TIME WITH US AND FOR
REMINDING US THAT WE ARE NOT
ALONE IN THIS TIME OF TRAGEDY,
THAT THERE'S NOT JUST A COUNTRY
STANDING BEHIND US, THAT THERE'S
A WORLD STANDING BEHIND US.
THOSE WORDS I KNOW AS DIFFICULT
AS THEY WERE TO HEAR FOR SOME,
BROUGHT MUCH CONSOLATION TO ALL.
I WANT TO THANK OUR GOVERNOR AND
ALL THE STATE OFFICIALS WHO HAVE
BEEN BY OUR SIDE SINCE DAY ONE.
THEY HAVE BEEN A REMARKABLE
REMINDER TO US OF THEIR HUMANITY
AND THEIR CARE FOR US.
BUT MOST OF ALL, I WANT TO THANK
AN INCREDIBLE FIRST-SELECT WOMAN
WHO'S LED US THROUGH THE MOST
DARK PERIODS OF OUR LIVES.
IN THE STORMS OF THE PAST YEARS
RAVAGED OUR COMMUNITY WITHOUT
POWER FOR DAYS, I THOUGHT THOSE
WERE THE HARDEST DAYS OF PAT'S
LIFE, BUT WHEN I SAW HER FRIDAY
IN FRONT OF SANDY HOOK SCHOOL, I
REALIZED THAT SHE'D MET THE MOST
DARK DAYS.
PAT, TO YOU, TO DR. ROBINSON, WE
THANK YOU FOR BEING LEADERS TO
US THROUGH THESE DIFFICULT
TIMES.
AND NOW THIS FINAL PART OF OUR
PRAYER IS FOR US, THE PEOPLE OF
NEWTOWN.
>> THESE ARE THE WORDS OF THE
APOSTLE PAUL AS HE WRITES TO THE
CHURCH AT ROME.
WHAT THEN SHALL WE SAY IN
RESPONSE TO THIS, IF GOD IS FOR
US, WHO CAN BE AGAINST US?
HE WHO DID NOT SPARE HIS OWN
SON, BUT GAVE HIM UP FOR ALL OF
US, HOW WILL HE NOT ALSO ALONG
WITH HIM GRACIOUSLY GIVE US ALL
THINGS?
WHO WILL BRING ANY CHARGE
AGAINST THOSE WHOM GOD HAS
CHOSEN, THAT IS GOD WHO
JUSTIFIES, WHO IS HE THAT
CONDEMNS?
CHRIST JESUS WHO DIED, MORE THAN
THAT WHO WAS RAISED TO LIFE, WAS
AT THE RIGHT HAND OF GOD AND IS
ALSO INTERCEDING FOR US.
WHO SHALL SEPARATE US FROM THE
LOVE OF CHRIST, SHALL TROUBLE OR
HARDSHIP OR PERSECUTION OR
FAMINE OR NAKEDNESS OR DANGER OR
SWORD AS IT IS WRITTEN FOR YOUR
SAKE, WE FACE DEATH ALL DAY
LONG, WE ARE CONSIDERED AS SHEEP
TO BE SLAUGHTERED.
KNOW IN ALL THESE THINGS WE ARE
MORE THAN CONQUERERS THROUGH HIM
WHO LOVED US, FOR I AM CONVINCED
THAT NEITHER DEATH, NOR LIFE,
NEITHER ANGELS, NOR DEMONS,
NEITHER THE PRESENCE, NOR THE
FUTURE, NEITHER ANY POWERS,
HEIGHT, NOR DEPTH, IN ALL
CREATION WILL BE ABLE TO
SEPARATE US FROM THE LOVE OF GOD
THAT IS IN CHRIST JESUS OUR
LORD.
>> AND SO WE STAND NOW IN PRAYER
FOR OURSELVES.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN, BUT OUR
SPIRITS ARE STRENGTHENED BY THE
POWER OF GOD'S GOODNESS AND HIS
EVER-CREATING LOVE AND BY THE
GENEROUS HEARTS OF A COMMUNITY
WHO TRULY CARES.
WE HAVE SHOWN TO THE WORLD OUR
COMPASSION.