JESUS [ BLEEP ] CHRIST.
I COME ON THE NEWS FOR TWO
SECONDS AND YOU WANT TO -- EVERY
TIME I DO AN INTERVIEW, A GUY
WANTS TO OPEN HIS [ BLEEP ]
MOUTH.
CAN'T YOU [ BLEEP ] A ROUTINE
HERE.
GO [ BLEEP ] YOURSELF, YOU KNOW
WHAT.
>> OH!
OH!
YEAH, THAT WAS ANDREW DICE CLAY
BEING INTERVIEWED, FOR SOME
REASON, ON THE NOW DEFUNCT
CNN-FN BY ALLAN CHERNOFF, WHO
DEFINITELY WOULD HAVE BEEN
BETTER OFF HOLDING A FISH
STANDING IN A BOAT.
WE'RE HOLDING OUT FOR SOME
MODERATE TO EXTREME
>>> OBAMA AND BAOEHNER ARE
FACE-TO-FACE.
THEY TROO TO STAVE OFF THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
>> SUSAN RICE OUT OF THE
RUNNING.
THE PRESIDENT'S U.N. AMBASSADOR
GIVES UP ON HER HOPES TO BE NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE.
>> AND BULLETS FLY AS THE CAMERA
ROLLS.
VIDEO CAPTURES THE MOMENT SHOTS
RING OUT ABOARD A TRAIN.
GOOD MORNING.
WELCOME TO "EARLY START" THIS
FRIDAY MORNING.
I'M CHRISTINE ROMANS.
>> I'M JOHN BERMAN.
IT IS 5:00 A.M. IN THE EAST.
>> WE HAVE BREAKING NEWS THIS
MORNING.
IT'S A BIG DEVELOPMENT IN THE
FIGHT AGAINST SYRIA AND A NEW
LEVEL OF U.S. INVOLVEMENT.
WE JUST LEARNED WITHIN THE PAST
FEW HOURS THE DEFENSE SECRETARY
LEON PANETTA SIGNED AN ORDER
SENDING TWO PATRIOT MISSILE
BATTERIES TO TURKEY.
THAT'S TO ASSIST THAT NATION IN
DEFENDING AGAINST ANY POLLIBLE
MILITARY ACTION BY SYRIA.
THIS MOVE WAS EXPECTED AS THE
CIVIL WAR IN SYRIA DESTABILIZES
THE ASSAD REGIME WITH EACH
PASSING DAY.
IN ADDITION TO THIS, 400 U.S.
TROOPS ARE GOING TO TURKEY.
THEY WILL BE DEPLOYED TO OPERATE
THE MISSILE BATTERIES.
CNN'S NICK PAYTON WALSH HAS THE
DEVELOPMENT.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING.
400 PERSONNEL WILL BE
ACCOMPANYING THE BATTERIES.
LET ME GIVE YOU HISTORY.
OVER THE PAST TWO MONTHS, WE SAW
SPORADIC EXCHANGES OF FIRE
ACROSS THE BORDER.
SYRIAN MILITARY FIRING INTO
TURKEY CAUSING OFTEN DESTRUCTION
AND DEATH.
TURKEY OFTEN RESPONDING.
THAT BROUGHT ABOUT THIS REQUEST
TO NATO FOR PATRIOT MISSILE
BATTERIES.
THEY'RE SUPPOSED TO BE THERE.
THIS PARTICULAR TYPE BETTER AT
TAKING OUT MISSILES IN THE SKY
RATHER THAN TAKING DOWN
AIRCRAFT.
BUT THIS MOVE PART OF A NATO
RESPONSE.
ALSO SUPPLIED BY GERMANY AND
HOLLAND WHOSE PARLIAMENT LAST
WEEK APPROVED THEIR
CONTRIBUTIONS.
THE U.S., THOUGH, OF COURSE,
PUTTING A NUMBER OF PEOPLE ON
THE GROUND.
MANY OBSERVERS SAYING THAT NOW
NATO HAS PHYSICAL TROOPS AND
PRESENCE IN THE AREA THAT IT
RISKS SOMEHOW BEING DRAGGED INTO
THIS PARTICULAR CONFLICT.
EVERYBODY IS STRESSING THESE ARE
PURELY THERE TO DEFEND TURKEY, A
STAUNCH NATO MEMBER.
JOHN?
>> THEY STILL COME AS THE U.S.
OFFERED DIPLOMATIC RECOGNITION
TO THE REBELS IN SYRIA AND WITH
400 U.S. TROOPS THERE, IT DOES
GIVE THE U.S. SOME SKIN IN THIS
GAME.
>> Reporter: ABSOLUTELY.
I DON'T THINK THE TROOPS WILL BE
INVOLVED.
SKIN IN THE GAME, CERTAINLY.
THE OBAMA ADMINISTRATION THOUGH
MANY SAY CAUGHT BETWEEN TWO
DIFFERENT SIDES HERE.
AT THE SAME TIME, THE DAY BEFORE
THEY GAVE SOME KIND OF LOWER
LEVEL DIPLOMATIC RECOGNITION TO
THE SYRIAN GOVERNMENT.
THE DAY BEFORE THAT THEY WERE A
TERROR GROUP, ONE OF THE MORE
HARD LINE PARTS OF THE REBEL
FRONT RESPONSIBLE FOR MANY
VICTORIES, CONSIDERED ISLAMIC
HARD-LINERS.
TO MANY DEGREES THEY'RE HEROES
BECAUSE THEY'VE BEEN TAKING OUT
SO MANY REGIME OUTPOSTS.
THE U.S. RESPONSE IN THE PAST,
48 HOURS.
SIGNIFICANTLY MORE COMPLICATED.
AND NOW AS YOU SAY, SKIN IN THE
GAME.
>> NICK PEYTON WALSH, WATCHING
ALL THE DEVELOPMENTS GOING ON.
THANK YOU.
>>> AND NOW THE FISCAL CLIFF.
THERE IS LITTLE PROGRESS AND A
WHOLE LOT OF FRANK.
HERE'S WHAT WE MEAN.
IN 18 DAYS WE GO OVER THE EDGE
TRIGGERING TAX HIKES AND
SWEEPING CUTS.
LAST NIGHT PRESIDENT OBAMA
CALLED JOHN BOEHNER AND ASKED
HIM TO MEET AGAIN AT THE WHITE
HOUSE.
THEY SPENT A LITTLE LESS THAN AN
HOUR AGO.
WAS IT A GOOD TALK?
WAS IT A PRODUCTIVE TALK?
AFTERWARD, BOTH SIDE SAID THEY
CALLED THEIR DISCUSSION FRANK
AND SAID THE LINES OF
COMMUNICATION REMAIN OPEN.
THAT TO BE FRANK DOESN'T SEEM TO
GET US ANYWHERE CLOSER TO A DEAL
THOUGH.
DANA BASH JOINS US FROM
WASHINGTON.
SPEAKER BOEHNER PLANS TO GO HOME
TO OHIO TODAY.
>> Reporter: THAT'S RIGHT.
HE IS ON HIS WAY IF NOT THERE
ALREADY.
AND, YOU KNOW, YOU TALKED ABOUT
THE WORD FRANK THAT WAS USED BY
BOTH PARTIES, BY THE WHITE HOUSE
AND BY THE SPEAKER'S OFFICE.
JUST LIKE THEY DID OVER THE
WEEKEND THEY PUT OUT IDENTICAL
STATEMENTS, REALLY ONE SENTENCE
STATEMENTS.
DIPLOMATIC TERMS, FRANK MEANS
NOT SO GOOD.
AND THAT'S THE SAME WORD THAT
THE SPEAKER USED A COUPLE DAYS
AGO TO DESCRIBE THEIR MEETING ON
SUNDAY WHICH WE UNDERSTAND FROM
SOURCES WAS PRETTY TENSE.
JUST THE FACT THAT THEY ONLY MET
FOR 50 MINUTES IS INDICATIVE OF
THE FACT THAT THE MEETING DIDN'T
PRODUCE VERY MUCH.
NOW I UNDERSTAND FROM DEMOCRATIC
SOURCES EARLIER IN THE DAY
YESTERDAY THAT THEY WERE GOING
TO TRY TO INVITE THE SPEAKER
OVER TO THE WHITE HOUSE TO GET
THINGS MOVING BEFORE HE WENT
HOME TO OHIO TO PERHAPS PUT A
FEW OF THE SPENDING CUTS THAT
THE SPEAKER HAS BEEN DEMANDING
ON THE TABLE TO TRY TO, YOU
KNOW, CUT A -- BREAK THIS
DEADLOCK.
DOESN'T SEEM LIKE THEY GOT VERY
FAR.
>> WE'VE HAD DEAD LOCKS BEFORE
IN WASHINGTON AND THEY'VE, YOU
KNOW, WITH MUCH PAIN BEEN
RESOLVED.
YOU TALKED TO TWO FORMER SENATE
MAJORITY LEADERS FROM OPPOSITE
SIDES OF THE AISLE ON HOW TO
MAKE A DEAL.
WHAT DID THEY SAY?
>> TALK.
I MEAN IT'S AS SIMPLE AS THAT.
JUST KEEP TALKING.
YOU'RE RIGHT, THESE WERE TWO
PEOPLE WHO WERE ON OPPOSITE
SIDES OF THE AISLE LEADING THE
SENATE FOR SIX YEARS TOGETHER.
TRENT LOTT THE REPUBLICAN, TOM
DASCHLE THE DEMOCRAT.
HERE'S WHAT THEY SAID ABOUT THE
ART OF DOING SOMETHING REALLY
REALLY TOUGH.
>> THERE WILL COME A MOMENT WHEN
THE SPEAKER IS GOING TO HAVE TO,
YOU KNOW, MAKE A DECISION ON
THAT AND THE PRESIDENT IS GOING
TO HAVE TO MAKE A DECISION ON
WHAT HE'S GOING TO DO IN RETURN
ON SPENDINGMENT BUT TH.
BUT THEY NEED TO DO IT IN
CONCERT.
YOU HAVE TO HAVE THE WINDS AND
THE BRASS COME TOGETHER.
>> HOLD HANDS AND JUMP OFF THE
CLIFF TOGETHER?
>> YEAH.
IT WILL BE MORE FUN ON THE WAY
DOWN.
AT LEAST YOU HAVE COMPANY.
>> AND I HAVE TO TELL YOU, JUST
IN THE HALLS OF CONGRESS TALKING
TO LAWMAKERS ALL DAY LONG EVERY
DAY, THERE IS REALLY A LOT OF
ANGST AND NOT A LOT OF OPTIMISM
THAT THEY'RE REALLY GOING TO GET
THIS DEAL DONE.
AND THAT REALLY IS A BIG, BIG
DIFFERENCE BETWEEN WHAT I
COVERED THOSE TWO MEN IN THE
LAST DECADE AND WHAT'S GOING ON
NOW.
USED TO BE YOU USED TO STAND IN
THE HALLWAYS AND WAIT TO SEE
WHEN THE DEAL WOULD GET DONE AND
WHAT WOULD IT LOOK LIKE?
AND NOW IT'S WILL THE DEAL GET
DONE?
AND IT REALLY IS A DIFFERENT
KIND OF ATMOSPHERE.
>> REMINDS ME KIND OF THE
GOVERNMENT SHUTDOWN IN '96.
WILL IT HAPPEN?
IT WILL NEVER HAPPEN AND THEN IT
HAPPENED AND THEN GOT RESOLVED.
DANA BASH, THANK YOU.
>> TO BE FRANK, NOT VERY GOOD
NEWS.
>>> THE OTHER MAMMOTH NEWS, OF
COURSE, IN WASHINGTON, THE
STUNNER FROM AMBASSADOR SUSAN
RICE.
SHE'LL MEET TODAY WITH THE
PRESIDENT AFTER TAKING HERSELF
OUT OF THE RUNNING TO BE THE
NEXT SECRETARY OF STATE N A
LETTER TO THE PRESIDENT, RICE
SAID, THE CONFIRMATION PROCESS
WOULD BE LENGTHY, DISRUPTIVE AND
COSTLY TO YOU AND OUR MOST
PRESSING NATIONAL AND
INTERNATIONAL PRIORITIES.
THAT TRADEOFF IS SIMPLY NOT
WORTH IT TO OUR COUNTRY.
PRESIDENT OBAMA TALKED ABOUT HER
DECISION LAST NIGHT.
>> I HADN'T MADE A DECISION
ABOUT WHO WOULD BE MY NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE.
THERE'S NO DOUBT THAT SUSAN WAS
QUALIFIED.
THERE ARE OTHER PEOPLE WHO ARE
QUALIFIED AS WELL.
HER INTEREST IS IN SERVING ME
BUT MOST IMPORTANTLY IN SERVING
THE COUNTRY.
AND SHE'S DONE AN OUTSTANDING
JOB.
SHE WILL CONTINUE TO BE ONE OF
THE TOP MEMBERS OF MY NATIONAL
SECURITY TEAM.
>> RICE DREW HEAVY CRITICISM
FROM REPUBLICANS OVER HER
STATEMENTS AFTER THE ATTACK ON
THE U.S. MISSION IN BENGHAZI IN
LIBYA WHEN SHE SAID THE VIOLENCE
STARTED OVER ANGER ABOUT AN
ANTI-MUSLIM FILM.
THE ATTACK NOW KNOWN TO BE
TERROR, KILLED U.S. AMBASSADOR
TO LIBYA CHRIS STEVENS AND THREE
OTHER AMERICANS.
IN FIVE MINUTES WE'RE GOING TO
TALK ABOUT NOW WHO IS IN THE
RUNNING TO BE THE NEXT SECRETARY
OF STATE.
I THINK THE SHORT LIST IS DOWN
TO ESSENTIALLY ONE.
>> THERE WILL BE A FUNERAL
SERVICE IN ST. LOUIS TODAY FOR
DALLAS COWBOYS FOOTBALL PLAYER
JERRY BROWN.
HE DIED IN A SUSPECTED DRUNK
DRIVING ACCIDENT ON SATURDAY.
HIS TEAMMATE AND FRIEND JOSH
BRENT WAS BEHIND THE WHEEL.
POLICE RELEASING THIS NEW VIDEO
OF THE WRECK AS WELL AS 911
CALLS THEY RECEIVED IN THE
MOMENTS AFTER IT HAPPENED.
>> I DON'T KNOW.
I JUST DROVE PAST IT.
IT'S LIKE IT JUST HAPPENED.
THE CAR WAS UP SIDE DOWN AND
THERE WAS SMOKE EVERYWHERE.
>> JOSH BRENT IS FREE ON
$500,000 BAIL.
HE'S FACING INTOXICATION
MANSLAUGHTER CHARGES.
>> PHILADELPHIA POLICE ARE
SEARCHING FOR TWO YOUNG MEN
INVOLVED IN A SHOOTING ABOARD AN
ELEVATED TRAIN.
THIS INCIDENT CAUGHT ON TAPE.
VIDEO CAPTURED A CONFRONTATION
BETWEEN A FEW YOUNG MEN WHO WERE
ARGUING OVER A BASEBALL GAME.
THAT'S WHEN ONE OF THE SUSPECTS
AS HE WAS LEAVING TURNED AND
FIRED A GUN, A HANDGUN INTO THE
TRAIN.
WOW.
LOOK AT THAT.
TWO PEOPLE WERE WOUNDED IN THIS
ATTACK.
>> CELEBRATIONS ON THE STREETS
OF PYONGYANG, NORTH KOREANS
CLINKING BEER MUGS AND DANCING
ON SIDEWALKS FOLLOWING THE
COUNTRY'S FIRST SUCCESSFUL
LAUNCH INTO SPACE.
EVEN THE SUPREME LEADER GOT INTO
THE ACT.
THE NORTH KOREAN GOVERNMENT
RELEASING THIS PHOTO OF THE
LAUNCH AS LEADERS IN WASHINGTON,
TOKYO AND SEOUL ALL CALL FOR
PUNISHMENT INSISTING THAT
SUCCESSFUL DEPLOYMENT MOVES
NORTH KOREANS ONE STEP CLOSER TO
BEING ABLE TO LAUNCH NUCLEAR
WEAPONS ACROSS THE PACIFIC.
>> SO THE BASKETBALL GAME
BETWEEN BLOOMINGTON SOUTH AND
ARLINGTON HIGH WOULD BE A
DISSERVICE TO BLOWOUTS.
THE TWO GIRLS TOOK THE FIELD AND
WHEN IT WAS OVER, BLOOMINGTON
HIGH CAME OUT ON TOP 107 TO 2.
>> MUST HAVE BEEN SOMETHING
WRONG WITH THAT SCOREBOARD.
>> THAT'S A DIFFERENCE OF 105
POINTS.
AIM ASSURED HERE.
THE ARLINGTON GIRLS COULD ONLY
MANAGE TWO FREE THROWS THE
ENTIRE CONTEST.
NOW AS YOU CAN IMAGINE, THE
BLOOMINGTON COACH, THE COACH
THAT SCORED 107 IS TAKING A LOT
OF HEAT ONLINE FOR PILING ON.
SOME PEOPLE CALLING FOR HIM TO
BE FIRED.
>> YOU'RE THE SPORTS GUY.
IF YOU'RE WINNING AND TEAM IS
GOOD, DO YOU KEEP SCORING THE
POINTS?
>> I'M A DAD, IF MY KIDS WERE
EVER ON THE SIDE, IT WOULD BREAK
MY HEART.
THAT'S ALL I CAN SAY.
I GUESS I JUST TOOK SIDES.
>>> IN THE 8:00 A.M. OF
"STARTING POINT," SOWE'RE GOINGO
TALK TO THE ARLINGTON TEAM.
SHE'S GOING TO TALK ABOUT WHAT
IT'S LIKE TO LOSE A GAME BY 105
POINTS.
>>> A TEXT MESSAGE ANGERS SOME
PEOPLE.
IT'S AN INTERESTING STORY AND
IT'S COMING UP.
[ Male Announcer ]
SPONGES TAKE YOUR MARK.
[ Female Announcer ]
ONE DROP OF ULTRA DAWN
HAS TWICE THE EVERYDAY
GREASE CLEANING INGREDIENTS
OF ONE DROP OF THE LEADING
NON-CONCENTRATED BRAND...
TO CLEAN 2X MORE GREASY DISHES.
DAWN DOES MORE.
SO IT'S NOT A CHORE.
CAN YOUR MOISTURIZER DO THAT?
[ Female Announcer ]
DERMATOLOGIST RECOMMENDED
Aveeno HAS AN OAT FORMULA,
NOW PROVEN
TO BUILD A MOISTURE RESERVE,
SO SKIN CAN REPLENISH ITSELF.
THAT'S HEALTHY SKIN FOR LIFE.
ONLY FROM Aveeno.
You know how painful heartburn
can be.
For fast, long lasting relief,
use doctor recommended
Gaviscon®.
Only Gaviscon® forms a
protective barrier that helps
block stomach acid from
splashing up-
relieving the pain quickly.
Try fast, long lasting
Gaviscon®.
SINCE AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL
WAS FOUNDED BACK IN 1894,
THEY'VE BEEN COMMITTED
TO PUTTING CLIENTS FIRST.
HELPING GENERATIONS
THROUGH TOUGH TIMES.
GOOD TIMES.
NEVER TAKING A BAILOUT.
THERE WHEN YOU NEED THEM.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
OVER THE CENTURIES.
THE STRENGTH OF
A GLOBAL FINANCIAL LEADER.
THE HEART OF
A ONE-TO-ONE RELATIONSHIP.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
TRY RUNNING FOUR.NING
A RESTAURANT IS HARD,
FORTUNATELY WE'VE GOT INK.
IT GIVES US 5X THE REWARDS
ON OUR INTERNET, PHONE
CHARGES AND CABLE,
PLUS AT OFFICE SUPPLY STORES.
REWARDS WE PUT RIGHT
BACK INTO OUR BUSINESS.
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
WE'VE EVER WANTED TO DO
AND INK HELPS US DO IT.
MAKE YOUR MARK
WITH INK FROM CHASE.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
>>> THE ATTACK OVER BENGHAZI
LEADS TO A SHOCKER.
SUSAN RICE IS TAKING HERSELF OUT
OF THE RUNNING.
SHE'LL NOT SUCCEED SECRETARY OF
STATE HILLARY CLINTON.
SHE EXPLAINED IN A LETTER TO
PRESIDENT OBAMA SAYING THE
CONFIRMATION PROCESS WOULD BE
LENGTHY, DISRUPTIVE AND COSTLY
TO YOU AND OUR MOST PRESSING
NATIONAL AND INTERNATIONAL
PRIORITIES.
THAT TRADEOFF IS SIMPLY NOT
WORTH IT TO OUR COUNTRY.
THOSE WORDS FROM SUSAN RICE.
FOREIGN AFFAIRS REPORTER IS IN
WASHINGTON WITH THE LATEST.
SUSAN RICE MEETING WITH THE
PRESIDENT TODAY.
>> THAT'S RIGHT, JOHN.
THEY'LL BE MEETING WITH THE
PRESIDENT AND HER -- PRESIDENT
OBAMA SAID AND HER AIDES TELL ME
THAT AMBASSADOR RICE WILL STAY
AT THE U.N. AND THAT SHE'LL
CONTINUE TO BE A VERY CLOSE
ADVISER TO THE PRESIDENT AND THE
PRESIDENT'S CABINET.
YOU KNOW, SOME OF THE AIDES SAID
SHE WAS UP FOR THE FIGHT WITH
THE SENATE.
SHE WAS UP FOR DEFENDING HER
POSSIBLE CANDIDACY BUT THEY DID
THE MATH, JOHN.
THEY SAW THAT THESE ATTACKS HAD
STOPPED BENGHAZI, THEY MORPHED
INTO OTHER AREAS.
THEY FELT IT DETRACTED FROM THE
MORE SUCCESSFUL WORK SHE DID
HAVE AT THE U.N. SUCH AS GETTING
REALLY TOUGH SANCTIONS ON IRAN
AND REALLY FIGHTING FOR ACTION
IN LIBYA, U.S. MILITARY ACTION
TO GET RID OF MUAMMAR QADDAFI.
LET'S TAKE A LISTEN TO WHAT
AMBASSADOR RICE SAID YESTERDAY
ABOUT WHY SHE RESIGNED.
>> I WITHDREW MY NAME BECAUSE I
THINK IT'S THE RIGHT THING FOR
THE COUNTRY.
I THINK IT'S THE RIGHT THING FOR
THE PRESIDENT.
AND PUTTING THOSE THINGS
TOGETHER, THAT MAKES IT THE
RIGHT THING FOR ME AND MY
FAMILY.
>> SO SHE'LL STAY ON THE TEAM,
JOHN, AND SOME PEOPLE SAY THAT
SHE COULD HAVE A FUTURE ROLE IN
THE ADMINISTRATION, A DIFFERENT
ROLE LATER ON.
>> THEY'VE BEEN FAIRLY EXPLICIT
SHE COULD END UP AS NATIONAL
SECURITY ADVISER ONE DAY AND
THEN PERHAPS THIS FOUR-YEAR TERM
GET ANOTHER SHOT AT BEING
SECRETARY OF STATE.
AS FOR WHO WILL BE THE NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE, THE SHORT
LIST SEEMS TO BE ESSENTIALLY
DOWN TO ONE PERSON.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
ONE PERSON WHO THE SENATE HAS
SAID WOULD BE EASILY CONFIRMED.
IT'S THEIR COLLEAGUE SENATOR
JOHN KERRY.
THE CHAIRMAN OF THE SENATE
FOREIGN RELATIONS COMMITTEE.
SENATOR KERRY IS SEEN AS SOMEONE
WHO'S REALLY HAS A LOT OF
STATURE IN THE WORLD.
HE'S BEEN DOING FOREIGN POLICY
FOR MANY DECADES.
IF YOU REMEMBER, HE WAS ONE OF
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S KIND OF
MENTORS DURING THE DEBATE
PROCESS, PREPPING HIM FOR
DEBATES.
AND HE'S SEEN AS SOMEONE WHO HAS
RELATIONSHIPS, JOHN, AROUND THE
WHOLE WORLD WITH WORLD LEADERS,
SOMEONE THAT REALLY COULD BE
VERY EFFECTIVE IN U.S.
DIPLOMACY.
>> HE MADE IT CLEAR HE WANTED
THIS JOB FOR A LONG, LONG TIME.
>> NO SECRET.
>> YOU KNOW, MASSACHUSETTS,
THAT'S WHERE SENATOR JOHN KERRY
SERVES.
HE WOULD HAVE TO GIVE UP HIS
SEAT THERE.
THERE IS A LOT OF TALK ABOUT WHO
WOULD SUCCEED HIM.
WHAT WOULD HAPPEN UP THERE?
>> THAT IS ONE OF THE
CONSIDERATIONS IN WHETHER THEY
WOULD TAP SENATOR KERRY FOR THE
POST.
THE FRONT-RUNNER FOR THAT SEAT
IS SCOTT BROWN.
HE'S A FORMER SENATOR FROM
MASSACHUSETTS WHO JUST WON HIS
RE-ELECTION.
SO I THINK THAT THE
ADMINISTRATION WAS LOATHE TO
GIVE UP THE SENATE SEAT.
BUT THEY DID PICK UP A COUPLE
SEATS FOR THE PAST ELECTION.
SO IF THEY DO PICK SENATOR
KERRY, THEY FEEL THEY CAN LIVE
WITHOUT IT.
HE MADE NO SECRET HE WANTS THE
JOB.
AND PRACTICALLY THE ENTIRE
SENATE SAID HE'D BE EASILY
CONFIRMED AND AN EXCELLENT
CHOICE.
CERTAINLY PRESIDENT OBAMA WOULD
LOVE TO GET THAT BEHIND HIM.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
THERE WOULD BE A SPECIAL
ELECTION IN MASSACHUSETTS, 145
DAYS AFTER KERRY GIVES UP HIS
SEAT AND SCOTT BROWN EASILY THE
FRONT-RUNNER IN THAT RACE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>>> IT IS 17 MINUTES AFTER THE
HOUR THIS FRIDAY MORNING.
LET'S GET YOU UP TO DATE WITH
THE MORNING'S TOP STORIES.
PRESIDENT OBAMA, HOUSE SPEAKER
JOHN BOEHNER GOING FACE-TO-FACE
BEHIND CLOSED DOORS OF THE WHITE
HOUSE AGAIN.
WITH 18 DAYS REMAINING BEFORE
AMERICA GOES OVER THE FISCAL
CLIFF, THERE IS STILL NO SIGN OF
A DEAL.
BOTH SIDES CALLING YESTERDAY'S
TALKS FRANK AND INSISTING THE
LINES OF COMMUNICATION REMAIN
OPEN.
>>> A MAN FATALLY SHOT HIMSELF
INSIDE A CLERK'S OFFICE AT THE
FEDERAL COURTHOUSE IN
BIRMINGHAM, ALABAMA.
THE U.S. MARSHAL SERVICE SAYS HE
WORKED IN THE BUILDING AND
SLIPPED A GUN PAST SECURITY
BECAUSE HE USED AN EMPLOYEE
ENTRANCE, NOT A PUBLIC ONE.
VISITORS HAVE TO PASS THROUGH
METAL DETECTORS.
POLICE SAY NO ONE IN THE
COURTHOUSE WAS THREATENED.
>>> SO THE UNIVERSITY OF MIAMI
HAS APOLOGIZED FOR A TEXT MESS
AN GAFFE SENT OVER TO EMERGENCY
NOTIFICATION NETWORK.
IT WARNED OF A BLACK MAN ON
CAMPUS AND WHAT HE WAS WEARING.
THAT TEXT RAISED EYEBROWS AS
THERE ARE MANY BLACK MEN ON
CAMPUS.
THE COMPLETE TEXT SHOULD HAVE
SAID THAT WAS THE DESCRIPTION OF
A MAN WANTED FOR STEALING A
STUDENT'S LAPTOP.
IT WAS A GAME OF HOT POTATO
THURSDAY NIGHT.
THE EAGLES HAD A PUNT BLOCKED BY
THEIR OWN TEAMMATE.
THEY LOST AT HOME TO THE
BENGALS.
THEY DROP TO 4-10.
CINCINNATI KEEPS PLAY-OFF HOPES
ALIVE BY IMPROVING TO 8-6.
>> THAT WAS AWFUL.
LOOK OUT FOR THE BENGALS.
THEY CAN PLAY SOME FOOTBALL.
>>> ALL RIGHT.
IT IS 18 MINUTES AFTER THE HOUR
NOW.
TIME FOR "EARLY READ."
WE'RE REVEALING THE STORY IN THE
CHICAGO SUN TIMES WHERE ONE
LAWMAKER IS PROPOSING FINES AS
HIGH ASED 1 E$1,000 AND SIX MONN
JAIL FOR PIGEON FEEDERS.
HE SAID HE'S TIRED OF SEEING
PARTS OF TOWN BEING SEEN FROM A
MOVIE FROM "THE BIRDS."
HE SAID BIRD DROPPINGS A QUARTER
INCH THICK IN SOME SPOTS.
THERE ARE CULL PRETTIES THAT
FEED THE BIRDS THREE OR FOUR
POUNDS OF BREAD FOUR TIMES A
DAY.
ONE OF THESE FEEDERS IS KNOWN AS
THE PIGEON LADY.
>>> ALL RIGHT.
GET BACK HERE WITH MY DRIVEWAY.
POLICE ARRESTED A MAN ACCUSED OF
STEALING SOMEONE'S DRIVEWAY.
BRICK BY BRICK.
THE NEIGHBOR CALLED DEPUTIES
REPORTING TWO PEOPLE WITH TRUCK
REMOVING THE BRICKS.
ABOUT 300 SQUARE FEET OF THEM
ARE GONE AND A FEW DAYS LATER
THEY CAME BACK FOR MORE.
POLICE FOUND 40 TO 50 BRICKS IN
THE BED OF THE GUY'S TRUCK.
I ONCE DID A STORY ABOUTHE
LANDSCAPING THAT KEPT
DISAPPEARING FROM PEOPLE'S
HOUSES.
THEY WOULD PUT BRAND NEW
LANDSCAPING IN, LIKE A 200 TREE
AND THE NEXT DAY IT IS GONE.
>> THAT IS FAIRLY AGGRESSIVE
THOUGH, STEALING SOMEONE'S
DRIVEWAY.
>>> FOR A LOOK AT ALL OF OUR TOP
STORIES, HEAD TO OUR BLOG.
YOU CAN ALSO FOLLOW US ON
TWITTER.
YOU SHOULD FOLLOW US ON TWITTER
AND FACEBOOK.
JUST SEARCH FOR EARLY START/CNN.
>> ONE MORE WAY --
>> DON'T TELL ME ANY MORE WAYS.
>> THERE ARE A LOT OF WAYS THE
FISCAL CLIFF IS GOING TO COST
YOU.
WHAT HAPPENS TO YOUR PAYCHECK IF
THERE'S NO DEAL IN WASHINGTON?
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO LIKE IT.
[ Female Announcer ]
WHAT IF THE NEXT BIG THING,
ISN'T A THING AT ALL?
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
CONNECTING
TO THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
PROGRESSIVE DIRECT AND OTHER
CAR INSURANCE COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
CALL OR CLICK TODAY.
as part
of a heart healthy diet.
That's true.
...But you still have to go
to the gym.
♪ The one and only, Cheerios
>>> YOU'RE LOOKING AT NEW YORK
CITY RIGHT THERE.
>> IS THAT ICE RINK?
>> I HOPE THEY'RE NOT SKATING
NOW.
THAT WOULD BE SPOOKY AT 5:30
A.M. SKATING.
THAT'S A NICE SHOT.
AND THEY'LL BE SKATING OVER THE
COURSE OF THE DAY.
IT IS YOUR LUCKY DAY.
WHY?
CHRISTINE IS MINDING YOUR
BUSINESS THIS MORNING.
>> STOCK FUTURES ARE UP A LITTLE
BIT.
WORRIES OF THE FISCAL CLIFF ARE
STILL AROUND DESPITE UPBEAT DATA
YESTERDAY.
MILDLY POSITIVE DATA IN THE U.S.
THE S&P 500 SNAPPED A SIX-DAY
WINNING STREAK YESTERDAY.
IN PART BECAUSE STILL CONCERNED
ABOUT PROGRESS IN THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
IF CONGRESS FAILS TO REACH A
DEAL ON THE FISCAL CLIFF, MORE
THAN TWO MILLION LONG TERM
UNEMPLOYED AMERICANS WILL SEE
THE FEDERAL JOBLESS BENEFITS
DISAPPEAR COME JANUARY 1st.
LONG TERM EMPLOYED, THOSE OUT OF
WORK FOR 40 WEEKS OR MORE
CURRENTLY MAKE UP 40% OF THE
UNEMPLOYED POPULATION.
MANY WILL LOSE FEDERAL BENEFITS.
THEY SERVE AS A LIFE LINE TO
MANY OF THE PEOPLE THAT HAVE
BEEN OUT OF WORK FOR SO LONG.
AND OF ALL THE FISCAL CLIFF
ISSUES, THERE'S ONE THAT MANY
MIDDLE CLASS AMERICANS WILL
CERTAINLY FEEL RIGHT AWAY.
THAT'S THE PAYROLL TAX HOLIDAY.
COMES DIRECTLY FROM YOUR
PAYCHECK AND FUNDS SOCIAL
SECURITY.
FOR THE FIRST TWO YEARS THEY'VE
BEEN PAYING A RATE OF 4.2%.
IN 2013, THAT RATE IS SET TO GO
BACK UP.
SOMEONE MAKING $50,000 A YEAR
WILL SEE $19 LESS IN THEIR
TAKE-HOME PAY PER WEEK.
PAYROLL TAX CUT, A SMALL PIECE
OF A FISCAL CLIFF PUZZLE WOULD
HAVE A DIRECT, DIRECT EFFECT ON
YOUR PAYCHECK, FOLKS.
>> BUT THIS IS THE PAYROLL TAX
CUT.
IT WASN'T REALLY PART OF THE
FISCAL CLIFF ISSUES.
THIS IS HAPPENING INDEPENDENTLY.
>> IT IS.
BUT THE PRESIDENT WOULD LIKE TO
CONTINUE THE PAYROLL TAX
HOLIDAY.
AND YOU'RE HEARING SOME MUMBLING
AROUND FROM SOME PEOPLE ON THE
RIGHT THAT THEY DON'T WANT TO
RAISE TAXES ON ANYBODY.
SO THERE'S SOME SOUL SEARCHING
GOING ON THE PAYROLL TAX CUT AND
WHETHER THAT WOULD STAY OR GO.
TWO MONTHS AGO, I WOULD HAVE
TOLD YOU NO WAY IT COMES BACK.
NOW, THEY'RE TALKING ABOUT IT
AGAIN.
I'M ON THE EDGE.
>> IN THEIR FRANK DISCUSSIONS.
>> YEAH, IN THEIR FRANK
DISCUSSIONS WITH OPEN LINES OF
COMMUNICATION.
>> WHICH HAVE BEEN VERY FRANK,
FRANKLY.
>>> POLICE CAUGHT ON THE TRAIL
OF A HOT READY REPORTED STOLEN
AND THIS DOES NOT END WELL.
WATCH THE DRAMATIC CONCLUSION
COMING UP.
IF YOU'RE LEAVING THE HOUSE
RIGHT NOW, YOU CAN WATCH US ANY
TIME FROM YOUR DESKTOP OR MOBILE
PHONE.
Capella University understands
rough economic times
have led to an increase in
clinical depression.
Drug and alcohol abuse is up.
And those dealing with grief
don't have access to the
professional help they need.
When you see these issues, do
you want to walk away or
step up?
With a degree in the field of
Counseling or Psychology from
Capella University, you'll have
the knowledge to make
a difference in the lives of
others.
Let's get started at
CAPELLA.EDU
SOMETHING THIS DELICIOUS
COULD ONLY COME FROM NATURE.
NOW FROM THE MAKER
OF SPLENDA SWEETENERS,
DISCOVER NECTRESSE.
THE ONLY 100% NATURAL,
NO-CALORIE SWEETENER
MADE FROM THE GOODNESS
OF FRUIT.
THE RICH, SWEET TASTE OF SUGAR.
NOTHING ARTIFICIAL.
♪
IT'S ALL THAT SWEET
EVER NEEDS TO BE.
NEW NECTRESSE.
SWEETNESS NATURALLY.
TRUST DURACELL TO POWER
THEIR DONATED TOYS?
DURALOCK POWER PRESERVE.
IT LOCKS IN POWER
FOR UP TO 10 YEARS IN STORAGE.
GUARANTEED.
DURACELL WITH DURALOCK.
TRUSTED EVERYWHERE.
>>> THE U.S. SAYS THEY WILL SEND
MISSILES AND TROOPS TO THE AREA
BUT NOT TO THE REBELS.
>> A WHITE HOUSE ONE-ON-ONE AS
THE FISCAL CLIFF LOOMS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND SPEAKER
BOEHNER MEET AGAIN 18 DAYS TO
GO.
>> PUSH COMES TO SHOVE ON THE
FLOOR OF PARLIAMENT.
HOW THIS BRAWL BROKE OUT BETWEEN
MEMBERS OF THE SAME PARTY.
IT'S NOT EVEN PARTISAN
BICKERING.
THIS IS THE SAME PARTY.
>> THAT'S DEPRESSING.
>> THE GOOD NEWS IS IT'S NOT
PART OF THE BIG RING.
>>> IT IS 30 MINUTES PAST THE
HOUR.
>> OUR BREAKING NEWS THIS
MORNING.
A MAJOR DEVELOPMENT IN THE
SYRIAN CIVIL WAR AND THE NEW
LEVEL OF U.S. INVOLVEMENT.
OVERNIGHT DEFENSE SECRETARY LEON
PANETTA SIGNED AN ORDER SENDING
TWO PATRIOT MISSILE BATTERIES TO
TURKEY TO ASSIST THAT NATION IN
DEFENDING AGAINST ANY POSSIBLE
MILITARY ACTION BY SYRIA.
THIS MOVE WAS EXPECTED AS SYRIAN
CIVIL WAR DESTABILIZES THE ASSAD
REGIME WITH EACH PASSING DAY.
400 U.S. TROOPS ARE GOING TO BE
DEPLOYED TO OPERATE THESE
MISSILE BATTERIES.
TURKEY, OF COURSE, BORDERS SYRIA
AND THOUSANDS OF REBELS AND
REFUGEES FROM SYRIA HAVE FLED TO
TURKEY FOR SAFETY.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA AND HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER MEETING FOR
NEARLY AN HOUR YESTERDAY EVENING
IN A FISCAL CLIFF SHOWDOWN.
WITH 18 DAYS REMAINING BEFORE WE
GO OVER THE EDGE, BOTH SIDES ARE
SAYING THAT "LINES OF
COMMUNICATION REMAIN OPEN."
MOST OF US HAVE BEEN STRESSING
OVER THE THOUSANDS OF EXTRA
DOLLARS YOU MAY HAVE TO FORK
OVER TO UNCLE SAM NEXT YEAR.
ALONG WITH SEQUESTRATION COME
SWEEPING SPENDING CUTS, TOO.
HERE'S CNN PENTAGON
CORRESPONDENT CHRIS LAWRENCE.
>> Reporter: TO HEAR THE
PENTAGON TELL IT --
>> SEQUESTRATION, THEREFORE, IF
IT WERE ALLOWED TO HAPPEN, WOULD
INTRODUCE SENSELESS CHAOS.
>> Reporter: THE FISCAL CLIFF --
>> SEQUESTRATION WILL HAVE A
CHAOTIC INFECT ON THE FORCE.
IS AKIN TO ARMAGEDDON.
>> WHAT I WORRY ABOUT IS BEING
BLINDSIDED BY A HUGE CUT BECAUSE
THEY DON'T HAVE THE STRENGTH OR
THE COURAGE OR THE GUTS TO DO
WHAT THEY HAVE TO DO.
>> HAPPY HOLIDAYS.
>> Reporter: THE CLIFF WOULD CUT
$500 BILLION IN DEFENSE SPENDING
BUT SPREAD OUT OVER THE NEXT TEN
YEARS.
WOULD THESE CUTS REALLY BE THAT
BAD?
>> ABSOLUTELY NOT.
>> Reporter: ANALYST BEN FREEMAN
SAYS THE PENTAGON CAN SURVIVE ON
A SMALLER BUDGET.
>> SEQUESTRATION HAPPENS, IT
WILL DROP A LITTLE BIT.
IT'S CERTAINLY NOT CATASTROPHIC
OR DOOMSDAY OR ANY OF OTHER SORT
OF HIGH PENITENTIARYB HYPERBOLE.
>> Reporter: PERHAPS THE NAVY
HAS TO BUY LESS ADVANCED FIGHTER
JETS.
OR THE PENTAGON WOULD HAVE TO
CUT THE NUMBER OF SOLDIERS AND
MARINES BACK TO THE LEVELS
BEFORE 9/11.
>> SEQUESTRATION WOULD RISK
HOLLOWING OUT OUR FORCE.
>> Reporter: PENTAGON OFFICIALS
SAY GOING OVER THE CLIFF WOULD
ACTUALLY LEAVE THEM A TRILLION
DOLLARS IN THE HOLE BECAUSE IT
COMES ON TOP OF CUTS THEY HAVE
ALREADY BUDGETED FOR.
>> WE'VE PUT IN PLACE $487
BILLION IN SAVINGS OVER THE NEXT
TEN YEARS.
>> Reporter: ARE THESE CUTS THE
SAME SORT OF BUDGET CUTS THAT
YOU AND I THINK OF WHEN WE THINK
OF CUTTING OUR BUDGET?
>> I CALL THEM PHANTOM CUTS.
IT'S NOT A REAL SAVING.
>> Reporter: FREEMAN SAYS THE
PENTAGON IS COUNTING MONEY THAT
IT WAS PROJECTING TO SPEND AS
SAVINGS.
WHICH HE SAYS, ISN'T THE SAME AS
SIMPLY SPENDING LESS.
>> BUT THIS IS THE WAY D.C. DOES
MATH.
IT'S UNFORTUNATE THAT YOU AND I
CAN'T DO OUR TAXES LIKE.
THAT BUT IT'S THE WAY THEY SEEM
TO DO BUSINESS HERE.
>> Reporter: A SENIOR DEFENSE
OFFICIAL ADMITS THAT EVERYONE AT
THE PENTAGON FROM THE SECRETARY
ON DOWN IS ON AUTOPILOT TO
DEFEND THEIR BUDGET.
EVEN THOUGH HE FEELS THAT THEY
NEED PEOPLE TO GO IN AND
CHALLENGE THEIR COSTS, HE ARGUES
THAT'S BETTER DONE OVER TIME,
NOT FORCED ON THEM BY THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
CHRIS LAWRENCE, CNN, THE
PENTAGON.
>>> AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE MEETS
WITH PRESIDENT OBAMA TODAY AFTER
MAKING A STUNNING ANNOUNCEMENT.
SHE'S OUT OF THE RUNNING TO
SUCCEED OUTGOING SECRETARY OF
STATE HILLARY CLINTON.
FEW REPUBLICANS CRITICIZED HER
OVER STATEMENTS SHE MADE AFTER
THE ATTACK ON THE U.S. MISSION
IN BENGHAZI.
THE ATTACK KNOWN TO BE TERROR
KILLED THE U.S. AMBASSADOR TO
AMERICA, CHRIS STEVENS.
SHE MADE TELEVISION INTERVIEWS
AND SAID IT APPEARED TO COME
FROM AN ANDY ISLAM FILM.
>> THE MALL OUTSIDE PORTLAND
WHERE A GUNMAN KILLED TWO PEOPLE
ON TUESDAY, A THIRD PERSON KRIT
UKLY HURT.
THE GUNMAN JACOB ROBERTS TOOK
HIS OWN LIFE.
HIS MOTIVE IS STILL NOT CLEAR.
ROBERTS' AUNT RAISED HIM AFTER
HIS MOTHER DIED AND CALLS
HERSELF HIS MOM.
SHE SAYS HE LOST HIS WAY AFTER
AN INJURY.
>> JAKE WAS GOING TO BE A
WARRIOR.
HE WAS GOING TO BE A HERO.
AND HE WAS GOING TO JOIN THE
MARINES.
AND THEN HE BROKE HIS FOOT AND
HE COULDN'T BE A MARINE BECAUSE
HE GOT FIVE PINS IN HIS FOOT.
SO HE COULDN'T BE A MARINE
ANYMOREMENT AND THEN HE LOST
PURPOSE.
HE LOST, LIKE -- THAT IS WHAT HE
WAS GOING TO DO.
>> THERE WILL BE A CANDLELIGHT
VIGIL TONIGHT OUTSIDE THE MALL.
>>> DRAMATIC DASH CAM VIDEO OF A
POLICE CHASE IN SOUTH CAROLINA
THAT HAD A DEADLY ENDING.
DEPUTIES PURSUING THIS MUSTANG
EARLIER THIS MONTH AFTER IT HAD
BEEN REPORTED STOLEN.
THEY SAY THE DRIVER 27-YEAR-OLD
BRIAN MADDEN LOST CONTROL AFTER
TRYING TO TAKE A CURVE AT 26
MILES AHOUR.
HE WAS EJECTED AND HIS PASSENGER
HAD TO BE AIRLIFTED TO THE
HOSPITAL.
>>> SO THERE IS NOTHING LIKE A
GOOD POLITICAL FIGHT.
BUT THIS ONE TURNED INTO A BRAWL
ON THE FLOOR OF UKRAINE'S
PARLIAMENT.
THE SCUFFLE APPARENTLY BROKE OUT
AFTER MEMBERS OF THE OPPOSITION
PARTY ACCUSED TWO OF THEIR
MEMBERS OF PLANNING TO DEFECT TO
THE RULING PARTY.
THAT'S DRAMATIC.
>> HERE WE DON'T TALK TO EACH
OTHER IN WASHINGTON.
>>> IT'S NOT CLEAR WHETHER IT'S
DIET, MEDICINE, OR GENETICS,
JAPANESE ARE STILL THE
HEALTHIEST PEOPLE ON THE PLANET.
THE TOP FOUR HEALTHIEST
COUNTRIES FOR MEN ARE JAPAN
FOLLOWED BY SINGAPORE, SWINS
LAND AND SPAIN.
THE U.S. IS TIED WITH NORWAY FOR
29th PLACE.
JAPAN TOPS THE LIST FOR WOMEN,
FOLLOWED BY SOUTH KOREA, SPAIN,
AND SINGAPORE.
U.S. WOMEN FINISHED 33rd IN THE
TIE WITH ASTONA.
>> WE HAVE TO GET AHEAD OF
ASTONIA.
>> ALL RIGHT.
BARBARA STREISAND TALKING
ROMANCE AND POLITICS WITH PIERS
MORGAN.
THE HOLLYWOOD ICON SAYS SHE'S
NEVER BEEN IN LOVE WITH A
REPUBLICAN AND NEVER COULD BE.
SHE'S A BIG PRESIDENT OBAMA
SUPPORTER AND SAYS THE ONE THING
THAT MAKES HER PROUDEST IS HIS
SUPPORT FOR WOMEN AND BARBARA
STREISAND HAS A PARTICULAR WOMAN
IN MIND TO SUCCEED THE
PRESIDENT.
>> WELL, WE'RE ONE OF THE LAST
COUNTRIES TO EVER THINK OF
HAVING A WOMAN BE PRESIDENT.
BUT I THINK THAT'S POSSIBLE NOW.
BUT IT WASN'T YEARS AGO.
>> DO YOU THINK HILLARY IS
LIKELY TO RUN?
>> I DON'T KNOW BUT I HOPE AFTER
A FOUR-YEAR REST THAT SHE WOULD
RUN BECAUSE SHE WOULD BE A GREAT
WOMAN PRESIDENT.
>> PIERS ASKED BARBARA STREISAND
TO NAME THE GREATEST ACTOR SHE'S
EVER SEEN.
HER ANSWER, MARLON BRANDO.
GOOD PICK.
>> I WOULD SAY SO.
>>> THE UNSEEN VICTIMS OF A
GROWING EPIDEMIC IN THIS
COUNTRY.
COMING UP, PRESCRIPTION DRUG
ABUSE AND THE IMPACT ON PEOPLE
WHO NEVER EVEN POP A PILL.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN IT COMES TO
THE FINANCIAL OBSTACLES
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAND.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
GOVERNOR OF GETTING IT DONE.
YOU KNOW HOW TO DANCE...
WITH A DEADLINE.
AND YOU...RENT FROM NATIONAL.
BECAUSE ONLY NATIONAL LETS YOU
CHOOSE ANY CAR IN THE AISLE...
AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE A FULL-SIZE
OR ABOVE,
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
THIS IS AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS, BUSINESS PRO.
YES, IT IS.
GO NATIONAL. GO LIKE A PRO.
>>> IT IS 32 DEGREES IN ATLANTA.
LUCKY FOR THEM, IT WILL GET TO
59 LATER IN THE DAY.
IN THE STATE OF KENTUCKY, MORE
THAN 86,000 CHILDREN ARE GROWING
UP WITHOUT THEIR PARENTS.
ONE OF THE MAIN REASONS MANY
HAVE BEEN ORPHANED, PRESCRIPTION
DRUG OVERDOSE.
EVERY 19 MINUTES IN THE U.S.
SOMEONE DIES THAT WAY.
AND SO MANY OF THOSE CASES THERE
ARE CHILDREN LEFT BEHIND.
CNN'S SANJAY GUPTA TAKES US TO A
COMMUNITY IN KENTUCKY THAT IS
WITNESS TO THIS DEVASTATION.
>> Reporter: IF THIS TOWN COULD
TALK, IT WOULD DESCRIBE A
SIMPLE, IDYLLIC LIFE.
A PROUD PEOPLE.
IT WOULD ALSO WHISPER A SOBERING
STORY ABOUT AN EPIDEMIC THAT IS
TEARING APART FAMILY --
>> I LOST MY DAD AND UNCLE TO
DRUG ABUSE.
>> Reporter: AFTER FAMILY.
>> I LOST BOTH MY UNCLE AND
COUSIN TO YEARS OF PRI XRIPGS
DRUG ABUSE.
>> Reporter: AFTER FAMILY.
>> I LOST BOTH MY MOTHER AND MY
GRANDMOTHER TO DRUG ABUSE.
>> Reporter: IT IS NOT UNCOMMON
TO HEAR STORIES LIKE THIS DAY IN
ROCK COUNTY, KENTUCKY.
>> YOU'RE CONSTANTLY HEARING OF
SOMEONE DYING BECAUSE OF ABUSING
PRESCRIPTION DRUGS.
>> Reporter: THIS 16-YEAR-OLD
AVERY BRADSHAW KNOWS THE STORY
ALL TOO WELL.
>> MY GRANDPA, HE JUST SET ME
DOWN AND TOLD ME THAT HE WAS
GONE.
>> Reporter: WHEN AVERY WAS 7,
HIS FATHER OVERDOSED ON OXY
COULD THE IN.
HIS MOTHER WAS IN AND OUT OF HIS
LIFE.
>> THE HARDEST PART OF GROWING
UP WITHOUT A DAD IS, LIKE, NOT
HAVING THAT MODEL FAMILY THAT
YOU ALWAYS SEE.
>> Reporter: HE'S LUCKY ENOUGH
TO LIVE WITH HIS GREAT
GRANDPARENTS.
IN THIS TOWN, THAT MODEL FAMILY
IS BEING REDEFINED.
>> THIS IS HAPPENING IN
ROCKCASTLE COUNTY EVERY WEEK.
IT IS HAPPENING IN EASTERN
KENTUCKY EVERY DAY.
IT'S LEAVING OUR COMMUNITIES IN
SHREDS AND WE'RE LEFT BEHIND TO
PICK UP THE PIECES FROM THAT.
>> Reporter: KAREN KELLY IS THE
EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF OPERATION
UNITE, A COMMUNITY COALITION
DEVOTED TO PREVENTING OVERDOSE
DEATHS IN KENTUCKY.
IN FACT, KENTUCKY IS THE FOURTH
MOST MEDICATED STATE IN THE
NATION.
IT HAS THE SIXTH HIGHEST RATE OF
OVERDOSE DEATHS.
AND ONE COUNTY ALONE --
>> HALF OF THE KIDS HAVE NO
PARENT IN THE HOME WHATSOEVER.
SO NOW WE'RE SEEING MANY RAISED
BY GREAT GRANDPARENTS BECAUSE
WE'VE LOST AN ENTIRE GENERATION
OF YOUNG PEOPLE.
AND, YOU KNOW, THE KIDS ARE
REALLY THE ONES PAYING THE
BIGGEST PRICE.
>> IT'S STRESSFUL FOR KIDS AND
IT'S REALLY AN EMOTIONAL THING.
>> Reporter: DR. SANJAY GUPTA,
CNN, REPORTING.
>> I ASKED HIM BEFORE WHY ARE
DOCTORS PRESCRIBING ALL OF THE
VERY HEAVY, HEAVY MEDICATIONS SO
FREQUENTLY?
THERE ARE SO MANY PRESCRIPTIONS
BEING WRITTEN.
YOU HAVE TO ALSO WONDER WHY ARE
WE TAKING ALL THESE DRUGS?
WHY ARE DOCTORS PRESCRIBING ALL
THE DRUGS?
>> THANKS TO SANJAY FOR THAT
REALLY SAT SAD PIECE.
>>> IT IS A ONE WAY MISSION ALL
THE WAY TO THE MOON.
NASA'S PLANS FOR A BIG CRASH
COMING UP.
IF YOU'RE LEAVING THE HOUSE
RIGHT NOW, YOU CAN WATCH US ANY
TIME ON YOUR DESKTOP OR MOBILE
PHONE.
VICTOR! VICTOR!
I GOT YOUR
CAMPBELL'S CHUNKY SOUP.
MOM?
WHO'S MOM?
I'M THE GIANTS MASCOT.
THE GIANTS DON'T HAVE
A MASCOT!
OHHH! EAT UP!
NEW JAMMIN JERK CHICKEN SOUP
HAS TASTY PIECES OF CHICKEN
WITH RICE AND BEANS.
HMMM.
FOR GIANT HUNGER!
THANKS MOM!
SEE YA!
WHOAA...OOPS!
MOM?
I'M OK.
GRANDMA?
HI SWEETIE!
SHE OPERATES THE HEAD.
[ Male Announcer ]
CAMPBELL'S CHUNKY SOUP.
IT FILLS YOU UP RIGHT.
TIME FOR CITI PRICE REWIND.
BECAUSE YOUR DAUGHTER REALLY
WANTS THAT PINK CASTLE THING.
AND YOU REALLY DON'T WANT
TO PAY MORE THAN YOU HAVE TO.
ONLY CITI PRICE REWIND
AUTOMATICALLY SEARCHES
FOR THE LOWEST PRICE.
AND IF IT FINDS ONE, YOU GET
REFUNDED THE DIFFERENCE.
JUST USE YOUR CITI CARD
AND REGISTER YOUR PURCHASE
ONLINE.
HAVE A SUPER SPARKLY DAY!
OK.
[ Male Announcer ] NOW ALL
YOU NEED IS A MAGIC CARRIAGE.
CITI PRICE REWIND.
START SAVING
AT CITI.COM/PRICEREWIND.
>>> IT IS 48 MINUTES AFTER THE
HOUR.
LET'S GET YOU UP TO DATE ON THE
MORNING'S TOP STORIESMENT STILL
NO SIGN AF DEAL IN THE FISCAL
CLIFF SHOWDOWN.
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND JOHN BOEHNER
DID MEET FOR 50 MINUTES
YESTERDAY BEHIND CLOSED DOORS AT
THE WHITE HOUSE.
BOTH SIDES CALLED THE TALKS,
JOHN, FRANK.
BOTH SAID IT WAS FRANK.
AND THEY SAID THE LINE OF
COMMUNICATIONS REMAIN OPEN 18
DAYS BEFORE HIGHER TAXES AND
SPENDING CUTS KICK IN.
FRANK IN WASHINGTON MEANS
NOTHING HAPPENED.
>> CAN WE GET BEYOND FRANK?
WE'VE HAD ENOUGH FRANK SO FAR.
>> FRANK, YOU'RE NOT INVITED TO
THE NEXT MEETING.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> INVESTOR SUSAN RICE MEETS
WITH PRESIDENT OBAMA AFTER
ANNOUNCING SHE'S OUT AS
CONTENDER FOR SECRETARY OF
STATE.
SHE TOOK HERSELF OUT OF THE
RUNNING IN A LETTER TO PRESIDENT
OBAMA.
KEY REPUBLICANS BLASTED RICE
OVER STATEMENTS SHE MADE AFTER
THE SIEGE ON THAT U.S. MISSION
IN BENGHAZI IN LIBYA.
IT IS KNOWN TO BE A TERROR
ATTACK.
FOUR AMERICANS INCLUDING THE
U.S. AMBASSADOR TO AMERICA CHRIS
STEVENS KILLED IN THAT ATTACK.
>>> STUDENTS IN GEORGIA DON'T
GET DEGREES, THEIR SCHOOLS RISK
LOSING DOLLARS.
THEY FUND HIGHER EDUCATION BASED
ON GRADUATION RATES.
THIS NEW POLICY COULD FORCE
PUBLIC COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES
IN GEORGIA TO IMPROVE STUDENT
PERFORMANCE.
THAT'S THE GOAL.
>>> MISSION ACCOMPLISHED ON THE
MOON.
SO NOW A PAIR OF ROBOTIC TWIN
PROBES WHICH HAVE BEEN MAPPING
THE SURFACE OF THE MOON ARE SET
TO BE DESTROYED.
NASA'S PLAN ALL ALONG.
THEY'RE RUNNING LOW OF FUEL.
ON MONDAY THE PROBES WILL CRASH
IN A A MOUNTAIN.
>> THANKS, ROBOTS.
>>> AN 85-YEAR-OLD GREAT
GRANDMOTHER IN IOWA HAS FINALLY
ACHIEVED A PERSONAL GOAL.
SHE EARNED HER GED.
EARLIER THIS WEEK LOIS HOUSELOG
WALKED ACROSS A COMMUNITY
COLLEGE STAGE AND FINALLY EARNED
HER DIPLOMA.
>> IT'S REALLY EXCITING FOR ME
BECAUSE IT'S SOMETHING I ALWAYS
WANTED TO DO AND NEVER REALLY
FELT LIKE I HAD THE TIME.
I HOPE THAT PEOPLE WOULD BE
INSPIRED BY MY STORY.
I DON'T NEED IT.
BUT IT'S SOMETHING I WANTED.
>> HOUSELOG SAYS A LOT OF KIDS
HER AGE DIDN'T GO TO HIGH SCHOOL
BECAUSE THERE WAS NO SCHOOL
BUSES AND THE NEAREST SCHOOL IS
SEVEN MILES AWAY.
THE HARDEST PART OF THE TEST IS
MATH.
I HOPE SHE HAD AN AWESOME
GRADUATION PARTY.
>> I WILL TELL YOU, AS AN IOWA
NATIVE, SOME OF THE SMARTEST
PEOPLE I KNOW ARE PEOPLE WHO,
YOU KNOW, MAYBE DROPPED OUT OF
SCHOOL TO WORK ON THE FARM.
NEVER REALLY GOT THE CHANCE OR
DIDN'T GO TO SCHOOL.
SMART, SMART, SMART.
AND NOW SHE'S GOT THE GED TO
SHOW IT.
>> GOOD FOR HER.
>>> MEET CLIFF THE BEAGLE.
CLIFF IS THE FIRST BACTERIA
TESTING DOG IN THE WORLD.
HE CAN SNIFF OUT A HIGHLY
CONTAGIOUS BACTERIA CALLED
C-DIP.
THEY CAN SPREAD QUICKLY THROUGH
HOSPITALS.
THEY KILL AT LEAST 14,000
AMERICANS EACH YEAR TESTING FOR
THE INFECTIONS IS TIME
CONSUMING.
BUT CLIFF'S SENSITIVE SNIFFER
CAN DETECT THE TOXIN IN SECONDS.
WHEN HE FINDS AN INFECTED SPA E
PATIENT, CLIFF JUST COPS A
SQUAT.
>> CLIFF SOUNDS COOL.
>> HE SITS DOWN.
HE SITS DOWN.
PETE IS SHOWING ME WHAT THAT
MEANS.
>> NICE TO HEAR ABOUT CLIFF.
THANK YOU FOR THAT.
THAT DOES SOUND COOL.
>>> STORMY WEATHER RIGHT NOW IN
THE SOUTHWEST.
>> WHO IS SHOWING PEOPLE HOW TO
COP A SQUAT?
>> I THOUGHT WHAT DOES THAT
MEAN?
THEN PETE VERY HELPFULLY -- OUR
FLOOR MANAGER SHOWS ME.
>> LOVE YOU, BUT -- GOOD
MORNING, GUYS.
HEY, VIDEO -- WHO SAYS IT
DOESN'T RAIN IN SAN DIEGO?
FOLKS WHO LIVE THERE YESTERDAY
ARE LIKE YEAH, IT DOES.
THEY GOT A MONTH'S WORTH OF RAIN
IN -- WELL, LESS THAN A COUPLE
HOURS.
THIS HAPPENED.
SWIFT WATER RESCUE TEAMS ARE
OUT.
RUSH HOUR WAS A NIGHTMARE.
THE WATER IN SOME CARS WAS UP
AND OVER PAST THE WHEEL WELLS.
SO A DANGEROUS SITUATION THERE
WITH SOME THUNDERSTORMS BEING
REPORTED ACROSS SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA.
ALSO THUNDERSTORMS BEING
REPORTED YESTERDAY IN LAS VEGAS.
THAT WAS THE 25th DAY THEY SAW
THUNDERSTORMS THIS YEAR.
THE RECORD IS 26.
SO A LOT OF THUNDERSTORMS IN
VEGAS.
YOU HAD RECORD RAINFALL OF A
QUARTER INCH IN SAN DIEGO.
YOU HAD 1.56 INCHES OF RAINFALL.
YUMA, YOU HAD RECORD RAIN AS
WELL.
THE RAIN IN THROUGH PHOENIX.
IT IS SNOWING THROUGH FLAGSTAFF,
GETTING INTO THE GRAND CANYON AS
WELL.
THIS SYSTEM WILL SLOWLY SPIRAL
ITS WAY INTO THE FOUR CORNERS
AND BRING WITH IT MORE IN THE
WAY OF SOME HEAVY SNOW.
SOME OF IT WILL BE OVER THE SAN
JUANS OF SOUTHWEST COLORADO.
THEY'LL TAKE THAT FRESH POWDER,
FOR SURE.
THE SOUTH SIDE OF THE SYSTEM
WILL HAVE WIND AS WELL WITH
WINDS GUSTING TO 60 MILES AN
HOUR.
AHEAD OF THAT, WARM AND SUNNY.
A NICE CHILL IN THE AIR TO GET
YOU IN THE MOOD FOR THE SEASON
ACROSS THE EAST COAST.
THAT'S A QUICK CHECK ON WEATHER.
"EARLY START" COMING RIGHT BACK.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
I TELL THEM DENTURES ARE
VERY DIFFERENT TO REAL TEETH.
THEY'RE ABOUT 10 TIMES SOFTER
AND MAY HAVE SURFACE PORES
WHERE BACTERIA CAN GROW
AND MULTIPLY.
POLIDENT
IS SPECIFICALLY DESIGNED
TO CLEAN DENTURES DAILY.
ITS UNIQUE MICRO-CLEAN FORMULA
KILLS 99.9%
OF ODOR CAUSING BACTERIA
AND HELPS DISSOLVE STAINS,
CLEANING IN A BETTER WAY
THAN BRUSHING WITH TOOTHPASTE.
THAT'S WHY I RECOMMEND
USING POLIDENT.
[ Male Announcer ] POLIDENT.
CLEANER, FRESHER,
BRIGHTER EVERY DAY.
[ Male Announcer ] POLIDENT.
TRY RUNNING FOUR.NING
A RESTAURANT IS HARD,
FORTUNATELY WE'VE GOT INK.
IT GIVES US 5X THE REWARDS
ON OUR INTERNET, PHONE
CHARGES AND CABLE,
PLUS AT OFFICE SUPPLY STORES.
REWARDS WE PUT RIGHT
BACK INTO OUR BUSINESS.
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
WE'VE EVER WANTED TO DO
AND INK HELPS US DO IT.
MAKE YOUR MARK
WITH INK FROM CHASE.
Progresso.
In what world do potatoes,
bacon and cheese
add up to 100 calories?
Your world.
♪
[ whispers ]
Real bacon...
Creamy cheese...
100 calories...
[ Chef ] Ma'am
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
>>> WELCOME BACK.
56 MINUTES PAST THE HOUR,
CHRISTINE ROMANS ALONG WITH JOHN
BERMAN.
TAKING A LOOK AT THE TOP CNN
TRENDS ON THE WEB THIS MORNING.
>> WE'RE TALKING BASEBALL.
BIG MOVES OVERNIGHT.
THE ANKLES LANDING TANGELS SIGN
HAMILTON TO A FIVE YEAR, $125
MILLION DEAL.
THEY STOLE HIM AWAY FROM THE
TEXAS RANGERS.
HAMILTON JOINS A LINEUP THAT HAS
ALBERT PUJOLS IN IT, THEY SIGNED
HIM LAST OFF-SEASON AND THE BEST
YOUNG PLAYER IN THE GAME AS FAR
AS I'M CONCERNED, MICHAEL TROUT
COMING OFF ONE OF THE BEST
ROOKIE SEASONS IN DECADES.
HERE'S THE THING, THE ANGELS
NEED PITCHING.
THEY ALREADY SCORED A TON OF
RUNS.
THE LAST THING THEY NEED IS
ANOTHER BIG HITTER.
THIS MAY NOT HAPPEN THEM.
>> $125 MILLION, FIVE YEARS,
IT'S WORTH IT, RIGHT?
>> I WOULD SAY THAT IS MONEY I
WOULD TAKE.
>> YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'D TAKE HALF THAT.
>> THE ELDERLY WOMAN THAT RUINED
A 200-YEAR-OLD JESUS FRES HE
COULD IN A CHURCH.
SHE IS NOW DECIDED TO START
SELLING HER OWN ART.
80-YEAR-OLD PUT HER LATEST
CREATION ON EBAY'S SPANISH
WEBSITE.
THE PAINTING IS CURRENTLY
ATTRACTING BIDS OF ABOUT $1,000.
MONEY FROM THE WINNING BID WILL
REPORTEDLY BE DONATED TO A ROMAN
CATHOLIC CHARITY.
SO THAT 15 SECONDS TURNED INTO A
FULL MINUTE.
>> BEST IN BLOATED ART.
>>> ALL RIGHT.
TALK ABOUT PUTTING PEOPLE ON THE
SPOT.
A COUPLE OF STUDENTS AT BYU,
THEY HAD A LITTLE FUN THIS
HOLIDAY WITH STUDENTS STAGING A
FAKE CHRISTMAS SURVEY UNDERNEATH
SOME SURPRISE MISTLETOE.
IT CAME DOWN SORT OF FROM THE
SKY.
THEY MANAGED TO GET A FEW PECKS
OUT OF IT AND ONE OPEN PALMED
SLAP.
CHECK THIS OUT.
>> IS THAT MISTLETOE.
>> YEAH.
>> LIKE OVER THE DOOR?
>> YEAH, I GUESS SO.
>> NO.
>> OR WOULD YOU.
>> WOULD I?
>> YEAH?
>> I'VE NEVER DONE IT.
>> BUT YOU WOULD DO IT?
>> I WOULD DO IT.
>> OKAY.
>> WHOA.
HEY.
>> MERRY CHRISTMAS.
>> THANK YOU.
>> WELL, ALL RIGHT, I'LL GO FOR
IT.
>> OKAY.
GREAT.
>> WHOA!
>> I WASN'T SURE ABOUT THE
KISSES.
IT LOOKS LIKE THEY WERE GOING IN
FOR EXTRA.
AND THAT ONE, BOOM.
>> I JUST KEEP WALKING.
ALL RIGHT.
NOBODY IS SAFE FROM LATE NIGHT
HOSTS, NOT TAYLOR SWIFT OR THE
L.A. LAKERS ON HONEST ABE.
CHECK OUT LAST NIGHT'S BEST
ZINGERS.
>> TODAY'S TAYLOR SWIFT'S 23rd
BIRTHDAY.
TAYLOR SAYS SHE WANTS TO SPEND A
QUIET EVENING AT HOME BREAKING
UP WITH SOMEONE.
>> DOCTORS IN PENNSYLVANIA ARE
REPORTING THAT SOME THERAPY DOGS
CAN PREDICT DEATH.
HAVE YOU HEARD ABOUT THIS?
THIS IS UNBELIEVABLE.
THE DOGS CAN SENSE IF SOMEONE'S
DYING AND THEY WON'T GO INTO
THAT ROOM IF SOMEONE IS DYING IN
THERE.
IN FACT, THE OTHER NIGHT TWO OF
THE DOGS ARE STANDING OUTSIDE
THE LAKERS LOCKER ROOM.
THEY WOULDN'T GO IN.
>> HBO IS PLANNING A NEW MOVIE
SIMILAR TO GAME CHANGE BUT BASED
ON THE 2012 ELECTION.
YEAH, THE NETWORK SAID THEY'RE
NOT SURE WHO WILL PLAY MITT
ROMNEY AND THEN MITT ROMNEY WAS
LIKE, HEY, I'M NOT DOING
ANYTHING.
>> STEVEN SPIELBERG'S MOVIE
"LINCOLN" HAD THE MOST
NOMINATIONS OF ANY FILM THIS
YEAR, SEVEN.
"LINCOLN" WAS NOMINATED FOR BEST
DIRECTOR, BEST ACTOR AND BEST
BEARD WITHOUT A MUSTACHE.
>> HE IS NOMINATED FOR A SONG HE
WROTE FOR "MAGIC MIKE."
HE SPENT A LOT OF TIME MAKING
SURE THE WORDS ALL RHYME, ALL
RHYME, ALL RHYME.
>> ALL RIGHT, "EARLY START"
CONTINUES RIGHT NOW.
>>> BREAKING NEWS THIS MORNING
ON THE WAR IN SYRIA.
THE U.S. NOW COMMITTING MISSILES
AND TROOPS TO THE REGION.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA AND SPEAKER
BOEHNER FACE-TO-FACE.
BOEHNER FACE TO FACE.
THE PRESIDENT AND THE SPEAKER
TRYING AGAIN IN PERSON TO STAVE
OFF THAT FISCAL CLIFF.
>>> SUSAN RICE, OUT OF THE
RUNNING.
THE PRESIDENT'S U.N. AMBASSADOR,
GIVES UP ON THE HOPES TO BE THE
NEXT SECRETARY OF STATE.
GOOD MORNING, WELCOME TO "EARLY
START."
I'M CHRISTINE ROMANS.
ZORAIDA IS OFF THIS MORNING.
>> I'M JOHN BERMAN.
6:00 A.M. IN THE EAST.
>>> WE DO HAVE BREAKING NEWS.
A MAJOR STEP BY THE UNITED
STATES CONCERNING THE FIGHT
AGAINST SYRIA.
WE LEARNED OVERNIGHT THAT LEON
PANETTA SIGNED AN ORDER SENDING
TWO PATRIOT MISSILE BATTERIES TO
TURK
TURKEY TO ASSIST.
THIS WAS EXPECTED AS THE CIVIL
WAR IN SYRIA CONTINUES.
400 U.S. TROOPS WILL BE DEPLOYED
TO OPERATE THESE MISSILE
BATTERIES.
JUST OVER THE BORDER FROM SYRIA.
NICK PAYTON WALSH JOINS US FROM
BEIRUT.
WHAT IS THE LATEST?
>> PRECISELY WHERE THE BATTERIES
ARE GOING TO BE.
HUNDREDS OF U.S. TROOPS THERE TO
ASSIST IN THE OPERATION.
TWO FROM THE UNITED STATES,
GERMANY EXPECTED SHORTLY TO
APPROVE TWO BATTERY OF ITS OWN
WITH HUNDREDS OF GERMANS TO
ASSIST THEIR OPERATION AND ALSO
HOLLAND CONTRIBUTING TO.
LET'S GIVE YOU THE BACK STORY.
IN THE PAST FEW MONTHS,
EXCHANGES OF FIRE, ACCUSED OF
SHELLING INTO TURKEY, CAUSING
DESTRUCTION AND DEATH.
TURKEY FIRING BACK.
LEADING TO TURKEY ASKING NATO,
WHICH IT'S A MEMBER TO SEND THIS
KIND OF ASSISTANCE.
PATRIOT MISSILES GOOD AT TAKING
OUT MISSILE SHELLS AND USABLE
AGAINST AIRCRAFT TOO.
A SIGNIFICANT MOVE BY NATO.
NOW THEY HAVE SUBSTANTIAL
HARDWARE ON THAT VOLATILE BORDER
AND, OF COURSE, WOULD YOU HAVE
HEARD SECRETARY OF DEFENSE LEON
PANETTA'S COMMENTS THAT THE
UNITED STATES HAS CONTINGENCY
PLANS IN THE EVENT THEY SEE THE
ASSAD REGIME PREPONDERANCING OR
USING CHEMICAL WEAPONS.
A SIGNIFICANT MOVE BY THE U.S.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
HARDWARE AND SKIN IN THE GAME
WITH 400 U.S. TROOPS.
NICK PATON WALSH, THANK YOU FOR
JOINING US.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA GOING FACE
TO FACE IN THE WHITE HOUSE
AGAIN, AND THE STAKES COULD NOT
BE HIGHER WITH 18 DAYS TO GO
UNTIL WE GO OVER THAT CLIFF.
TRIGGER MASSIVE TAX HIKES,
SPENDING CUTS AND HOUSE SET TO
GO HOME FOR THE HOLIDAYS TODAY.
YESTERDAY, PRESIDENT OBAMA
TELEPHONED SPOKER BOEHNER, AND
BOTH SIDES CALLED THE
CONSTITUTION FRANK AND SAID "THE
LINES OF COMMUNICATION REMAIN
OPEN."
SENIOR CONGRESSIONAL
CORRESPONDENT DANA BASH JOINS US
LIVE FROM WASHINGTON.
HOUSE MEMBERS SCHEDULED TO BREAK
FOR THE HOLIDAYS TODAY, BUT
THEY'VE BEEN TOLD THEY MAY HAVE
TO STAY LATE, YET SPEAKER
BOEHNER PLANS TO GO HOME TO
OHIO.
THEY HAVE AIRPORTS AND PHONES IN
BUT WHERE IS THE URGENCY AROUND
THIS?
>> THAT IS A GREAT QUESTION.
REALLY ACTUALLY IS STUNNING.
WITH REGARD TO THE HOUSE, THEY
WERE TOLD THAT THEY SHOULD COME
BACK AT A MOMENT'S NOTICE, AND
ALSO TOLD -- I WAS INFORMED BY
SEVERAL REPUBLICAN LAWMAKERS NOT
TO MAKE PLANS FOR CHRISTMAS.
SO YOU HAVE THIS MEETING
YESTERDAY.
IT WAS DONE AT THE LAST MINUTE
BY THE PRESIDENT TO TRY TO JUMP
START THINGS, BUT AS YOU SAID,
BOTH SIDES SAID THAT THE MEETING
WAS FRANK, WHICH IN WASHINGTON
SPEAK, MOSTLY DIP LO SPEAK MEANS
IT DIDN'T GO THAT WELL.
I SPOKE TO A DEMOCRATIC SOURCE
WHO SAID THERE WAS NO NEW
INFORMATION, NEW NO OFFERS ON
THE TABLE.
JUST A DISCUSSION OF WHAT EACH
SIDE HAS TO DO TO REACH
AGREEMENT WHICH IS VERY
SURPRISING, GIVEN THE FACT IT'S
NOT A SECRET WHAT BOTH SIDES
NEED TO DO.
REPUBLICANS NEED TO GIVE MORE ON
REVENUE.
DEMOCRATS NEED TO GIVE MORE ON
SPENDING CUTS AND THAT'S WHAT
THEY HAVE TO DO.
>> YOU OWN A SMALL BUSINESS IN
AMERICA, YOU ARE TRYING TO
FIGURE OUT HOW YOU WILL DO YOUR
PAYROLL IN THE BEGINNING OF THE
YEAR, SOFTWARE CHANGES THAT TAKE
MORE THAN A COUPLE OF WEEKS.
FOR SOME, THEY ARE ASSUMING WE
ARE GOING OVER THE CLIFF.
THEY WON'T BE ABLE TO GET IT
TOGETHER IN TIME FOR THE FIRST
PAYCHECKS IN JANUARY.
YOU TALK TO TWO FORMER SENATE
MAJORITY LEADERS FROM OPPOSITE
SIDES OF THE AISLE WHO KNOW HOW
TO TUESDAYLE AND MAKE A DEAL.
TELL US ABOUT THAT.
>> TRENT LOTT, AND TOM DASCHLE,
THEY HAVE TUSSLED OVER MANY
THINGS.
BALANCED BUDGET IN 1996, WELFARE
REFORM, YOU NAME IT.
BUT THEY ADMIT THINGS ARE VERY
DIFFERENT NOW.
POLITICIANS IS A LOT MORE
DIVISIVE.
BOTH MEN PREDICT THERE WILL BE A
DEAL, JUST A MATTER OF WHEN.
>> I FEEL HOPEFUL AT LEAST THAT
THEY WILL COME TO AN AGREEMENT.
THERE IS AN ARGUMENT YOU DON'T
WANT TO MAKE IT TOO EARLY,
BECAUSE THAT GIVES PEOPLE THAT
MAY NOT BE TOO HAPPY MORE TIME
TO UNDERMINE IT.
SO THE TEMPO AND TIMING IS
IMPORTANT.
>> I'VE HEARD PEOPLE SAY IN THE
LAST COUPLE OF DAYS, REPUBLICANS
AND DEMOCRATS, THAT THE TIME HAS
COME TO PUT OUR COUNTRY AHEAD OF
OUR PARTY AND THAT'S REALLY WHAT
IT'S GOING TO TAKE.
PUTTING THE COUNTRY AHEAD OF THE
PARTY.
>> PUTTING THE COUNTRY AHEAD OF
THE PARTY, AGAIN, FOR DEMOCRATS
THAT MEANS BITING THE BULLET,
SAYING, OKAY, WE'RE GOING TO CUT
ENTITLEMENT SPENDING.
FOR REPUBLICANS IT MEANS BITING
THE BULLET.
WHAT PEOPLE ON THE FILL SAY
FRANKLY PRIVATELY THEY SAY IT
WILL HAPPEN ANYWAY TO GIVE INTO
THE PRESIDENT ON THE WEALTH
INCREASES, MAYBE NOT UP TO
PREBUSH ERA PERCENTAGES OF 36%,
BUT EVERYBODY HAS A REALLY GOOD
IDEA OF WHAT THEY NEED TO DO TO
COME TO COMPROMISE.
A QUESTION OF WHERE THEY ARE ON
THE DEADLINE WHAT PEOPLE CAN
SWALLOW POLITICALLY.
>> I JUST GOT AN E-MAIL FROM A
POLITICAL STRATEGIST, WATCHES
WASHINGTON FOR BUSINESS.
HE CALLS THIS THE MOST
INCOMPETENT, DYSFUNCTIONAL,
GRIDLOCKED, CONSTIPATED CONGRESS
EVER.
AND NO CHANCE THAT THE FISCAL
CLIFF DEAL CAN BE COMPLETED BY
CHRISTMAS.
PROSPECTS ARE FADING FOR A
FRAMEWORK BY NEW YEAR'S EVE.
PEOPLE WHO HAVE BEEN WATCHING
THIS FOR BUSINESS, WHO HAVE BEEN
UPBEAT UNTIL NOW, SAY IT'S JUST
A MESS.
>> IT REALLY IS A MESS.
ALL SIDES DUG IN.
AND I LAUGH THERE, BUT IT
OBVIOUSLY IS NOT FUNNY IT WOULD
BE FUNNY IF IT WASN'T SO
SERIOUS.
IF IT WAS A MOVIE, YOU WOULDN'T
BELIEVE IT.
>> HA HA, NOT FUNNY.
HA HA, JUST UNBELIEVABLE.
>>> IN THE NEXT HALF HOUR, WE'LL
TALK ABOUT THE FISCAL CLIFF
INFIGHTING WITHIN THE REPUBLICAN
PARTY WHEN WE ARE JOINED BY TONY
PERKINS, PRESIDENT OF THE FAMILY
RESEARCH COUNCIL.
>>> OTHER BIG NEWS FROM
WASHINGTON, THE STUN FOREVER
AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE.
SHE'LL MEET WITH THE PRESIDENT
TODAY AFTER TAKING HERSELF OUT
OF THE RUNNING TO BE THE NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE IN A LETTER
TO THE PRESIDENT, RICE SAID THE
CONFIRMATION PROCESS WOULD BE
LENGTHY, DISRUPTIVE AND COSTLY
TO YOU AND TO OUR MOST PRESSING
NATIONAL PRIORITIES AND THAT
TRADEOFF IS SIMPLY NOT WORTH IT
TO OUR COUNTRY.
>> I MADE A DECISION ABOUT WHO
WOULD BE OUR NEXT SECRETARY OF
STATE.
SUSAN IS QUALIFIED.
HER INTEREST IS IN SERVING ME,
BUT MOST IMPORTANTLY TO SERVING
THE COUNTRY.
SHE WILL CONTINUE TO BE ONE OF
THE TOP MEMBERS OF MY NATIONAL
SECURITY TEAM.
>> RICE TRUE HEAVY CRITICISM
OVER HER STATEMENTS ON ATTACK OF
THE U.S. MISSION IN BENGHAZI.
SHE SAID THE ATTACK, YOU WILL
REMEMBER, KILLED U.S. AMBASSADOR
TO LIBYA CHRIS STEVENS AND THREE
OTHER AMERICANS.
>>> SIGNS OF PROCESS.
A NUCLEAR ARMS TALKS BETWEEN THE
UNITED NATIONS AND IRAN.
INSPECTORS FROM THE U.N.
INTERNATIONAL ATOMIC ENERGY
AGENCY ARE ASKING FOR ACCESS TO
THE SUSPECT PARSHAN MILITARY
SITE SOUTHEAST OF TEHRAN.
NO WORD ON IF THEY ARE MAKING
PROGRESS THERE.
MORE MEETINGS EXPECTED TO TAKE
PLACE IN MID-JANUARY.
>>> A HEARSAY BROUGHT THE
REMAINS OF JENNI RIVERA TO A
MORT WEAR IN LONG BEACH,
CALIFORNIA, LAST NIGHT.
FANS LINED UP OUTSIDE TO PAY
THEIR RESPECTS.
THE REMAINS WERE IDENTIFIED
THROUGH DNA TESTING.
THE SPANISH SINGER AND POSSIBLY
SIX OTHER PEOPLE WERE KILLED
WHEN A PRIVATE PLANE CRASHED IN
MEXICO.
THE COMPANY THAT OWNS THE JET IS
A DEFENDANT IN TWO OTHER
LAWSUITS.
COULD BE A YEAR BEFORE WE HAVE
THE RESULTS.
>>> AND POLICE SAY 23-YEAR-OLD
NICHOLAS WIEME, TAKING PICTURES
ON A HOTEL'S FAMOUS ONION SHAPED
ROOFTOP DOME, WHEN HE BECAME
WEDGED IN THE CHIMNEY IT TOOK
FIREFIGHTERS HOURS TO GET HIM,
BUT HE WAS PRONOUNCED DEAD 45
MINUTES AFTER THEY WERE ABLE TO
FREE HIM.
>> AWFUL.
>>> NOT EXACTLY POLITICAL
STATESMANSHIP.
A POLITICAL FIGHT TURNED INTO A
BRAWL.
PUSHING, SHOVING, PUNCHES.
IT STARTED AFTER MEMBERS OF THE
OPPOSITION PARTY ACCUSED TWO OF
THEIR MEMBERS OF PLANNING TO
DEFECT TO THE RULING PARTY.
I GUESS THE GOOD NEWS, IT'S
INTRA-PARTY BICKERING, NOT
PARTISANSHIP HERE IN THE
UKRAINE, LIKE WE HAVE HERE IN
THE U.S.
>> WOW.
AT LEAST THEY ARE TALKING.
>> YEAH.
>>> IF YOU BELIEVE THE DOOMSDAY
SCENARIO IN THE MAYAN CALENDAR,
HAVE YOU A CHANCE TO SQUEEZE IN
THE VACATION OF A LIFETIME.
PEOPLE ARE FLOCKING TO THE
YUCATAN PENINSULA, NOT SO MUCH
TO WITNESS THE END OF THE YEAR,
BUT TO TAKE IN THE RITUALS OF
THE MAYAN END OF THE CYCLE OF
TIME.
>> JUDGING BY THE NUMBER OF
HOTELS BEING BUILT AND TOUR
OPERATORS BEING CREATED, WE CAN
TELL THERE IS A LOT OF
EXPECTATION.
A FEW HOTELS IN TOWN ARE GIVING
DISCOUNTS, BECAUSE IT'S THE END
OF THE WORLD.
>> GOOD ADVERTISING FOR THE
MAYAN RUINS.
>> IT TURNS OUT TO BE A GREAT
BUSINESS STRATEGY.
>> LOOK AT THE BEAUTIFUL
PICTURES.
SOME PRETTY BEAUTIFUL STUFF DOWN
THERE.
EVEN IF THE WORLD ENDS ON THE
21st, IT WOULD GO OUT WITH THE
PARTY TO END ALL PARTIES.
>> THAT IS THE GOOD NEWS.
IF THE WORLD ENDS, I THINK IT'S
GOOD TO GO OUT WITH A PARTY.
>> BUT DON'T SPEND ALL OF YOUR
RETIREMENT MONEY.
>> GOOD ADVICE.
>>> COMING UP, SURVEILLANCE
VIDEO CAPTURES THE MOMENT SHOTS
RING OUT ON A TRAIN.
CHILLING, CHILLING STUFF.
I'M DONE!
"ARE YOU A COOL MOM?"
I'M GONNA FIND OUT.
[ Female Announcer ]
SWIFFER WETJET'S PADS
ARE BETTER THAN EVER.
NOW THEY HAVE THE SCRUBBING
POWER OF MR. CLEAN MAGIC ERASER
SO YOU DON'T HAVE TO GET DOWN
ON YOUR HANDS AND KNEES
TO SCRUB AWAY TOUGH,
DRIED-ON STAINS.
HEY, DO YOU GUYS THINK I'M
"MOMTACULAR" OR "MOMTROCIOUS"?
♪
[ Female Announcer ] SWIFFER.
NOW WITH
THE SCRUBBING POWER
OF MR. CLEAN
MAGIC ERASER.
SINCE AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL
WAS FOUNDED BACK IN 1894,
THEY'VE BEEN COMMITTED
TO PUTTING CLIENTS FIRST.
HELPING GENERATIONS
THROUGH TOUGH TIMES.
GOOD TIMES.
NEVER TAKING A BAILOUT.
THERE WHEN YOU NEED THEM.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
OVER THE CENTURIES.
THE STRENGTH OF
A GLOBAL FINANCIAL LEADER.
THE HEART OF
A ONE-TO-ONE RELATIONSHIP.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN DIARRHEA HITS,
KAOPECTATE STOPS IT FAST.
POWERFUL LIQUID RELIEF
SPEEDS TO THE SOURCE.
FAST.
[ Male Announcer ]
STOP THE UH-OH FAST
WITH KAOPECTATE.
>>> BREAKING NEWS RIGHT NOW OUT
OF CALIFORNIA.
A POWERFUL EARTHQUAKE HIT OFF
THE COAST.
HEARING IT WAS A 6.4 MAGNITUDE
EARTHQUAKE.
ABOUT 137 MILES SOUTH/SOUTHWEST
OF SAN CLEMENTE ISLAND,
CALIFORNIA.
AND 140 MILES SOUTH OF ST.
NICHOLAS, CALIFORNIA.
ON BAJA CALIFORNIA.
ROB MARCIANO JOINS US.
>> AT THIS POINT, 25 MINUTES
AGO, TWO REPORTS OF EARTHQUAKES.
ONE A 6.4 AS YOU MENTIONED.
ANOTHER A 6.1.
BOTH JUST OFF THE COASTLINE BY
ABOUT 100 MILES OR SO.
THE SMALLER ONE, A LITTLE BIT
CLOSER TO THE COAST.
THESE ARE STRONG ENOUGH AND
CERTAINLY CLOSE ENOUGH TO BE
FELT IN NOT ONLY BAJA
CALIFORNIA, BUT SAN DIEGO AREA,
LIKELY THE ISLANDS OFF L.A. AND
ALSO L.A. PROPER HERE, LIKELY NO
DAMAGE WITH THIS.
AND ALSO NO TSUNAMI WARNINGS
HAVE BEEN ISSUED WITH THIS.
TYPICALLY ANYTHING BELOW A SEVEN
SUN LIKELY TO TRIGGER THAT.
AN ACTIVE AREA WHERE THE PACIFIC
PLATE BUMPS INTO THE NORTH
AMERICAN PLATE.
NOTHING NEW FOR FOLKS WHO LIVE
IN SOUTHERN CAL.
ANYTHING OVER A 6 IS ENOUGH TO
WAKE UP THE MASSES AND I'M SURE
OUR VIEWERS HAVE FELT IT.
A 6.4 MAGNITUDE QUAKE AND 6.1, 1
100 TO 150 MILES.
OFF THE CALIFORNIA AND MEXICO
BORDER HERE JUST ABOUT 25
MINUTES AGO.
WE'LL REPLAY THE REPORTS TO UP.
>> IF YOU FELT THIS, FELT
SOMETHING, CAN YOU TWEET
US @EARLYSTARTCNN.
TWEET WHAT YOU ARE SEEING AND IF
YOU FELT ANYTHING.
THANKS, ROB.
>> ALL RIGHT.
>>> OTHER NEWS, WASHINGTON IS
STILL ABUZZ THIS MORNING FROM
THE DIPLOMATIC SHOCKER, U.S.
AMBASSADOR TO THE UNITED
NATIONS, SUSAN RICE, TAKING
HERSELF OUT OF THE RUNNING.
WILL NOT SUCCEED SECRETARY OF
STATE HILLARY CLINTON.
SHE EXPLAINED IT IN A LETTER TO
PRESIDENT OBAMA.
SHE SAID, THE CONFIRMATION
PROCESS WOULD BE LENGTHY,
DISRUPTIVE AND COSTLY TO YOU AND
TO OUR MOST PRESSING NATIONAL
AND INTERNATIONAL PRIORITIES.
THAT TRADEOFF IS SIMPLY NOT
WORTH IT TO OUR COUNTRY SHE
SAID.
WE HAVE THE LATEST FROM
WASHINGTON.
AND SUSAN RICE IS GOING TO MEET
WITH THE PRESIDENT TODAY.
>> SHE IS GOING TO MEET WITH THE
PRESIDENT TODAY, JOHN.
SHE SPOKE WITH HIM YESTERDAY
BEFORE SHE SENT THAT LETTER,
OBVIOUSLY, A VERY DISAPPOINTING
DAY FOR SUSAN RICE.
REALLY, HER WHOLE LIFE HAD
HELPED TO BE SECRETARY OF STATE.
I TALKED TO SOME OF HER AIDES
YESTERDAY.
THEY SAID SHE HAS BEEN THINKING
ABOUT IT FOR SEVERAL WEEKS.
SHE WAS UP, SHE THOUGHT ULTIM  E
ULTIMATELY SHE COULD BE
CONFIRMED.
AFTER THINGS STARTED PILING ON
BEYOND BENGHAZI, THEY DID THE
MATH AND THEY THINK SUSAN RICE
HAD A VERY GOOD RECORD AT THE
U.N.
SHE WAS INSTRUMENTAL IN PASSING
SANCTIONS ON IRAN, ON PUSHING
FOR U.S. ACTION IN LIBYA, AND A
LOT OF OTHER THINGS AND THEY
FEEL THIS WAS NOT ONLY A
DISTRACTION FOR THE PRESIDENT,
BUT A DISTRACTION FOR HER WORK
AT THE U.N.
LET'S LISTEN TO WHAT SUSAN RICE
SAID YESTERDAY ABOUT WHY SHE
WITHDREW HER NAME FROM
CONSIDERATION.
>> I DIDN'T WANT TO SEE A
CONFIRMATION PROCESS THAT WAS
VERY PROLONGED, VERY
POLITICIZED, VERY DISTRACTING
AND VERY DISRUPTIVE.
BECAUSE THERE ARE SO MANY THINGS
WE NEED TO GET DONE AS A
COUNTRY.
>> AND, JOHN, THE PRESIDENT SAID
AND RICE'S AIDES SAID SHE WILL
GO BACK TO THE U.N., CONTINUE
HER WORK.
A LOT GOING ON AS YOU KNOW.
NOT JUST ON SYRIA, THE ONGOING
CRISIS THERE.
BUT EFFORTS TO GET SOME
SANCTIONS AGAINST NORTH KOREA
AND A LOT OF OTHER HOTSPOTS,
JOHN.
>> AND THEY'VE MADE CLEAR AT THE
WHITE HOUSE, SHE HAS A ROLE
MOVING FORWARD, MAYBE ONE DAY AS
NATIONAL SECURITY ADVISER AND
MAYBE SECRETARY OF STATE DOWN
THE LINE.
THE NEXT SECRETARY OF STATE?
THAT COULD COME IN THE NEXT
COUPLE OF DAYS, AND THERE SEEMS
TO BE A SHORT LIST RIGHT NOW OF
ONE PERSON.
>> SENATOR JOHN KERRY, WHO HAS
MADE NO SECRET THAT HE WANTS THE
JOB, AND HIS COLLEAGUES IN THE
SENATE MADE NO SECRET THAT HE
WOULD BE EASILY CONFIRMED.
AS THIS WAS GOING ON WITH SUSAN
RICE, A LOT OF PEOPLE FLOATED
JOHN KERRY'S NAME THAT HE WOULD
BE A SUITABLE CANDIDATE.
HE HAS A LOT OF WORLD STATURE, A
LOT OF RELATIONSHIPS WITH WORLD
LEADERS AND IS SEEN AS SOMEONE
WHO CAN DO DELICATE DIPLOMACY
AND HAS IN MANY YEARS OF THE
OBAMA ADMINISTRATION BEEN GOING
OUT AS OF A KIND OF QUASIENVOY
IN AREAS OF AFGHANISTAN,
PAKISTAN, STIRRA AT ONE POINT,
SO CERTAINLY HE HAS THE CHOPS
FOR THE JOB.
OVER THE NEXT COUPLE OF DAYS, WE
COULD SEE A NOMINATION.
>> ALL RIGHT, ELISE LABOTT,
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>>> POLICE IN PHILADELPHIA
SEARCHING FOR TWO YOUNG MEN
INVOLVED IN A SHOOTING ON AN
ELEVATED TRAIN.
THIS CONFRONTATION WAS OVER A
BASKETBALL GAME.
ONE OF THE SUSPECTS AS HE WAS
LEAVING, TURNED, FIRED A HANDGUN
INTO THE TRAIN.
TWO PEOPLE ARE WOUNDED THERE.
>>> THE LAWSUITS ARE STARTING TO
SNOWBALL FROM THE SPINAL
MENINGITIS OUTBREAK.
THE BOSTON AREA PHARMACY IS
FACING AT LEAST 50 FEDERAL
LAWSUITS IN 9 STATES.
37 PEOPLE DIED AND MORE THAN 500
SICKENED AFTER GETTINGSTEROID
INJECTIONS.
THE COMPANY THATREPARED THEM
IS SAID TO HAVE BEEN NEGLIGENT.
>>> A DISABLED VET RECEIVED
ABOARD A DELTA FLIGHT LAST YEAR,
CHRISTIAN BROWN LOST BOTH LEGS
IN AFGHANISTAN.
ON THE FLIGHT, HE WAS CLUMSILY
WHEELED TO THE BACK OF THE
PLANE, HUMILIATED ACCORDING TO A
FELLOW VET.
WHEN OTHERS TRIED TO HAVE BROWN
MOVED TO FIRST CLASS, THE CREW
REFUSED TO ALLOW HIM TO MOVE UP
TO FIRST CLASS.
THEY SAID THEY HAD TO KEEP THE
AISLES CLEAR AND GET THE PLANE
GOING.
AND IN A STATEMENT, DELTA
SAIDITH INVESTIGATING THE
INCIDENT AND HOLDS SERVICE
MEMBERS IN HIGH REGARD.
BUT CLEARLY ANOTHER MILITARY
MEMBER ON THAT FLIGHT WROTE A
SORT OF SCATHING, SCATHING
PLAY-BY-PLAY OF WHAT HAPPENED
AND SAID IT WAS JUST
UNFORGIVABLE.
>> A SHAME.
>>> JUST ONE MORE WAY THE FISCAL
CLIFF COULD COST UP WHAT HAPPENS
TO YOUR PAYCHECK IF THERE IS NO
DEAL IN WASHINGTON.
MANY OF MY PATIENTS STILL CLEAN
THEIR DENTURES WITH TOOTHPASTE.
BUT THEY HAVE TO
USE SPECIAL CARE
IN KEEPING THE DENTURE CLEAN.
DENTURES ARE VERY DIFFERENT
TO REAL TEETH.
THEY'RE ABOUT 10 TIMES SOFTER
AND MAY HAVE SURFACE PORES
WHERE BACTERIA CAN MULTIPLY.
POLIDENT IS DESIGNED
TO CLEAN DENTURES DAILY.
ITS UNIQUE MICRO-CLEAN FORMULA
KILLS 99.9%
OF ODOR CAUSING BACTERIA
AND HELPS DISSOLVE STAINS,
CLEANING IN A BETTER WAY
THAN BRUSHING WITH TOOTHPASTE.
THAT'S WHY I RECOMMEND
USING POLIDENT.
[ Male Announcer ] POLIDENT.
CLEANER, FRESHER,
BRIGHTER EVERY DAY.
GOVERNOR OF GETTING IT DONE.
YOU KNOW HOW TO DANCE...
WITH A DEADLINE.
AND YOU...RENT FROM NATIONAL.
BECAUSE ONLY NATIONAL LETS YOU
CHOOSE ANY CAR IN THE AISLE...
AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE A FULL-SIZE
OR ABOVE,
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
THIS IS AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS, BUSINESS PRO.
YES, IT IS.
GO NATIONAL. GO LIKE A PRO.
>>> THAT IS NEW YORK CITY,
FOLKS.
SITTING RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE OF
THE NOW.
LOVELY LIGHTS OF NEW YORK.
THE FINANCIAL CAPITAL OF THE
WORLD.
WE'RE LUCKY BECAUSE CHRISTINE IS
MINDING YOUR, MINE, ALL OF OUR
BUSINESS THIS MORNING.
>> MINDING YOUR BUSINESS.
STOCK FUTURES UP SLIGHTLY THIS
MORNING, WORRIES ABOUT THE
FISCAL CLIFF PERSIST.
THEY UNDERMINE ANY KIND OF SMALL
GAINS WE GET.
S & P 500, SNAPPED A SIX-DAY
WINNING STREAK BECAUSE OF THOSE
CONCERNS ABOUT THE FISCAL CLIFF
AND DESPITE MODESTLY UPDATED
BUSINESS DATA.
CONGRESS FAILED TO REACH A DEAL
ON THE CLIFF?
2 MILLION LONG LIFE TERM
UNEMPLOYMENT AMERICANS WILL SEE
JOBLESS BENEFITS DISAPPEAR THE
FIRST WEEK OF JANUARY.
ANOTHER MILLION WILL LOSE THEM
THE NEXT WEEK.
THOSE WHO ARE OUT OF WORK 40
WEEKS OR LONGER, THAT MAKE UP
40% OF THE UNEMPLOYED
POPULATION.
AS YOU MIGHT EXPECT, FEDERAL
JOBLESS BENEFITS, A CRUCIAL
LIFELINE FOR THOSE WHO HAVE BEEN
OUT OF WORK 40 WEEKS OR MORE AND
ARE WAITING FOR THE ECONOMY TO
START CREATE ENOUGH JOBS TO
ABSORB THEM BACK IN CALL IT THE
PAYROLL TAX CLIFF.
OF ALL OF THE TAX ISSUES BEING
NEGOTIATED, ONE MANY MIDDLE
CLASS FAMILIES WILL FEEL.
THE PAYROLL TAX HOLIDAY.
MONEY THAT COMES DIRECTLY FROM
THE PAYCHECK IT FUNDS PAYROLLS
AND SOCIAL SECURITY.
THE LAST TWO YEARS, WORKERS
PAYING A RATE OF 4.2% OF THEIR
EARNINGS, UP TO 110,000 OR SO
INTO PAYROLL TAXES.
IN 2013, THE RATE WILL GO UP TO
6.2% ON WAGES UP TO $113,000.
TAKE A LOOK AT THIS SOMEONE
SAYING $50,000 WILL SEE $19 PER
LESS IN TAKE HOME PAY PER WEEK.
ONLY A SMALL PIECE OF THE FISCAL
CLIFF PUZZLE.
YEAR END, ALL OF THE THINGS
CHANGING, BUT COULD AFFECT YOUR
PAYCHECK IMMEDIATELY.
THE ONE THING YOU NEED TO KNOW
ABOUT YOUR MONEY TODAY?
HAVE YOU NOTICED, HAVE YOU
NOTICED, EVERYONE, GAS PRICES
FALLING 22 STRAIGHT DAYS NOW AND
MANY THINK THEY WILL CONTINUE TO
GO DOWN THE REST OF THE YEAR.
ACCORDING TO THE AUTOMOBILE
ASSOCIATION, THE AVERAGE PRICE
FOR A GALLON OF UNLEADED FALLING
TO $3.29.
A 4.2% DECLINE SINCE NOVEMBER
23rd.
GOOD NEWS FOR YOU HITTING THE
ROAD FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
>> WE COMPLAIN, COMPLAIN,
COMPLAIN, COMPLAIN, WHEN GAS
PRICES GO UP AND NEVER SAY THANK
YOU WHEN THEY GO DOWN.
>> STILL HIGHER THAN THEY WERE
LAST YEAR AT THIS TIME.
>> SO YOU'RE STILL COMPLAINING.
>>> DOES THE REPUBLICAN PARTY
HAVE A BRAND PROBLEM?
COMING UP, WE'LL TALK ABOUT THAT
WHEN WE ARE JOINED BY TONY
PERK
PERKINS, PRESIDENT OF THE FAMILY
RESEARCH COUNCIL AND TALKING
ABOUT THE FUTURE OF THE GOP AND
MUCH, MUCH MORE.
carols
in background ]
Aunt Sally's
singing again.
It's a tradition,
honey.
[ singing
Christmas carols ]
mmmm.
[ Female Announcer ]
Make new traditions
with Pillsbury Grands!
Cinnamon Rolls.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
TRY RUNNING FOUR.NING
A RESTAURANT IS HARD,
FORTUNATELY WE'VE GOT INK.
IT GIVES US 5X THE REWARDS
ON OUR INTERNET, PHONE
CHARGES AND CABLE,
PLUS AT OFFICE SUPPLY STORES.
REWARDS WE PUT RIGHT
BACK INTO OUR BUSINESS.
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
WE'VE EVER WANTED TO DO
AND INK HELPS US DO IT.
MAKE YOUR MARK
WITH INK FROM CHASE.
(Announcer) When Subaru owners
look in the mirror,
they see more than themselves.
So we celebrate our year-end
with the "share the love" event.
Get a great deal on a new Subaru
and 250 dollars goes to your
choice of five charities.
By the end of this, our fifth
year,
our total can reach almost 25
million dollars.
It's a nice reflection on us
all.
Now through January 2nd.
>>> AND ECON 101 AS THE FISCAL
CLIFF LOOMS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND SPEAKER
BOEHNER MEET.
>>> SHOW OF FORCE.
THE U.S. SAYS IT WILL SEND
MISSILES AND TROOPS, BUT NOT TO
THE REBELS.
>>> TOUGH CALL FOR SUSAN RICE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S U.N.
AMBASSADOR SAID SHE TOOK HERSELF
OUT OF RUNNING TO BE THE NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE.
WELCOME BACK TO "EARLY START."
I'M JOHN BERMAN.
>> I'M CHRISTINE ROMANS IN FOR
ZORAIDA SAMBOLIN.
A LOT GOING ON.
>>> LEON PANETTA SIGNED AN ORDER
SENDING TWO PATRIOT MISSILE
BATTERIES TO TURKEY TO ASSIST
THAT NATION IN PROTECTING ITSELF
FROM MILITARY ACTION BY SYRIA.
IN ADDITION, 400 U.S. TROOPS
WILL BE DEPLOYED TO OPERATE THE
MISSILE BATTERIES.
TURKEY BORDERS SYRIA.
THOUSANDS OF REFUGEES HAVE FLED
TO TURKEY FOR SAFETY.
AL QAEDA REMAINS THE MOST
SIGNIFICANT THREAT FACING
AMERICA TODAY ERIN BURNETT SAT
DOWN WITH THE DEFENSE SEBLCRETA
IN KANDAHAR.
>> YOU CAN REACH A POINT WHERE
YOU SO SIGNIFICANTLY WEAKEN AL
QAEDA THAT, YOU KNOW, ALTHOUGH
THERE MAY STILL BE A FEW PEOPLE
AROUND, THEY WON'T BE ABLE TO
CONDUCT THE OPERATIONS THAT THEY
HAVE CONDUCTED IN THE PAST AND
THEY CERTAINLY WON'T BE ABLE TO
PLAN THE KIND OF ATTACKS THAT
AMERICA HAD HAPPEN TO IT ON 9/11
AND THAT'S OUR GOAL TO MAKE SURE
IT DOESN'T HAPPEN AGAIN.
>> YOU TALK ABOUT AL QAEDA AND
WHERE IT IS --
>> PANETTA WENT ON TO TELL ERIN
WE HAVE TO GO AFTER THE GROUP IN
YEMEN AND SOMALIA.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA AND SPEAKER
BOEHNER MET AGAIN BEHIND CLOSED
DOORS THIS WEEK.
WITH THE HOUSE SET TO SKIP DOWN
FOR THE HOLIDAYS TODAY, NO SIGN
OF A DEAL.
HERE IS WHAT BOTH SIDES ARE
SAYING, CALLING YESTERDAY'S
TALKS FRANK AND INSISTING THE
LINES OF COMMUNICATION REMAIN
OPEN.
JOHN.
>> DESPITE SECRETARY BOEHNER AND
PRESIDE
OTHER LEADERS TAKING A HARD
LINE, OTHERS ARE SAYING THAT THE
LATEST INFIGHTING IS GOING
STRONG SINCE THE ELECTION LAST
MONTH, MANY ARE SAYING THE PARTY
HAS A BRANDING PROBLEM.
WE WANT TO BRING IN TONY
PERKINS, PRESIDENT OF THE FAMILY
RESEARCH COUNCIL TO TALK ABOUT
THE FUTURE OF THE REPUBLICAN
PARTY.
NO DEAL, A STALEMATE, AND THE
SPEAKER TAKING A HARDLINE ON
TAXES.
HAVE YOU BEEN UP ON CAPITOL HILL
THIS WEEK.
WHAT ARE YOU HEARING FROM PEOPLE
INSIDE THE PARTY?
>> I'M HEARING THAT UNLESS THERE
IS SPENDING CUTS -- ARE SPENDING
CUTS, THERE WON'T BE REVENUE
INCREASING, MEASURES TAKEN OR
SUPPORTED BY REPUBLICANS.
>> YOU DON'T THINK THERE'S A
DEAL ANY TIME SOON?
>> THE AMERICAN PEOPLE, A WALL
STREET JOURNAL POLL SHOWS 2/3 OF
THE PEOPLE SAY, YEAH, WE COULD
USE MORE TAXES, BUT THEY NEED TO
BE COUPLED WITH SPENDING CUTS.
I THINK PEOPLE REALIZE THAT
WE'VE COME TO A POINT IF WE
CONTINUE TO KICK THE CAN OF
FISCAL RESPONSIBILITY DOWN THE
ROAD, WE'RE GOING TO END UP
KICKING THE CAN AS A COUNTRY.
>> CAN I ASK YOU, WOULD YOU BE
WILLING TO DEAL WITH NEW
REVENUE, TAX INCREASES?
>> I THINK MOST AMERICANS WOULD.
I DON'T THINK THEY ARE TOTALLY
OPPOSED TO CLOSING LOOPHOLES IF
YOU WILL.
BOTTOMLINE, IT'S A TAX INCREASE.
>> WHAT ABOUT THE TOP TWO -- TWO
TAX RATES?
>> I THINK WHEN YOU LOOK AT
THAT, YOU HAVE TO REALIZE THAT
INCLUDES A LOT OF SMALL
BUSINESSES, IN FACT, THE BULK OF
SMALL BUSINESSES WHICH ARE --
SMALL BUSINESS IS THE BIGGEST
EMPLOYER IN THIS COUNTRY.
SO I THINK THAT'S PROBLEMATIC
FOR THE ECONOMY.
IT'S SELLING WELL FOR THE
PRESIDENT TO GO AROUND, LET'S
GET THE TOP WAGE EARNERS.
THOSE ARE SMALL BUSINESSES THAT
EMPLOYEE PEOPLE.
>> LET'S TALK ABOUT THE
REPUBLICAN PARTY IN GENERAL.
SENATOR JIM DEMINT TO LEAVE TO
GO BECOME HEAD OF THE HERITAGE
FOUNDATION.
A LOT OF REPUBLICANS DIDN'T SHED
MANY TEARS WHEN HE LEFT.
DEMINT A TEA PARTY FAVORITE.
SOME SAY A HARD LIFELINE
CONSERVATIVE.
IS THERE A DIVISION BETWEEN TEA
PARTY MEMBERS AND OTHER
REPUBLICANS?
>> THERE WAS CHEERING ON BOTH
SIDES.
CONSERVATIVES THINK HIM MORE
EFFECTIVE AT THE HERITAGE
FOUNDATION AND THE ESTABLISHMENT
CHEERING, AT LEAST FOR THE SHORT
TERM, THAT HE'S OUT OF THEIR
HAIR.
HE DID CHALLENGE THE
ESTABLISHMENT, WHICH IS -- LOOK,
YOU LOOK AT THE LAST TWO
PRESIDENTIAL ELECTIONS,
REPUBLICANS PUT FORTH MODERATE
CANDIDATES, AND THEY LOST.
MODERATES DON
MODERAT
MODERATES, THE GRASSROOTS AND
THE BASE OF THE PARTY, IF THEY
ARE GOING TO BE SUCCESSFUL, THEY
HAVE TO RETURN TO THE FOUNDING
PRINCIPLES, NOT RETREAT.
>> CONSERVATIVES LOSE TOO.
TODD AKIN LOSE, MURDOCH LOSE IN
INDIANA.
CONSERVATIVES LOSE TOO.
>> NO QUESTION, A BAD CYCLE FOR
REPUBLICANS AND YOU MENTIONED
TODD AKIN AND RICHARD MURDOCH,
WE'RE PREPARED FOR SOME OF THE
TOUGH ISSUES AND HOW TO TALK
ABOUT THE ISSUES SUCCESSFULLY.
OTHER CANDIDATES HAVE
SUCCESSFULLY TALKED ABOUT THEM.
>> LET'S TALK ABOUT THE SOLUTION
OF CERTAIN ISSUES.
51% OF AMERICANS SUPPORT GAY
MARRIAGE, 6 OF 10 YOUNG PEOPLE
SUPPORT GAY MARRIAGE.
BALLOT BOX, THREE STATES
APPROVED GAY MARRIAGE, OTHER
STATES ALLOW IT.
IS THERE AN EVOLUTION IN THIS
COUNTRY RIGHT NOW?
>> OVER 40 STATES THAT HAVE
MARRIAGE DEFINED IN THEIR STATE
LAWS AS A UNION BETWEEN A MAN
AND A WOMAN.
30 HAVE GONE TO AN EFFORT OF
PLACING IT INTO THEIR
CONSTITUTION.
FOUR STATES VOTED ON IT THIS
TIME, WHICH TRADITIONAL MARRIAGE
DID NOT PREVAIL.
I HARDLY THINK THAT WHAT WE SAW
IN THIS ELECTION IS A -- IS A
CONSENSUS, AS SOME HAVE
DESCRIBED ON SAME-SEX MARRIAGE.
LOOK, 40 YEARS AGO, AND COMING
UP NEXT MONTH, WILL BE 40 YEARS
OF ROE VERSUS WADE, THOSE UNDER
29 HAILED THAT AS A GREAT
DECISION BY THE COURT.
THAT SAME AGE CATEGORY, 18 TO 29
TONIGHT, ARE MORE PRO LEGAL THAN
THEIR PARENTS.
>> HAVE YOU BEEN IN THE NEWS
DEALING WITH UPS BECAUSE OF THE
BOY SCOUTS.
UPS ARE PULLING THEIR FUNDING
FOR THE BOY SCOUTS BECAUSE THEY
WILL NOT ALLOW GAY MEMBERS TO
HELP RUN THE BOY SCOUTS OR
INSIDE THE BOY SCOUTS.
WHY DID THE FAMILY RESEARCH
COUNCIL DO THIS?
>> THE BOY SCOUTS FOR OVER 100
YEARS, AS PART OF THEIR MORAL
CODE, HAS CHALLENGED BOYS TO BE
STRAIGHT AND UPSTANDING
CITIZENS.
>> STRAIGHT?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN BY THAT?
>> THEIR CODE IS MORLEY
STRAIGHT, THEY NOT ENGAGE IN
SEXUAL BEHAVIOR THAT THEY KEEP
THEMSELVES MORLEY CONDITIONED
AND MENTALLY SHARP AND THAT'S
THEIR CODE.
THEY HAVE HAD THIS POLICY LONG
RUNNING FOR GOOD REASON AND TO
HAVE AN ORGANIZATION SAY, LOOK,
WE WON'T GIVE YOU MONEY UNLESS
YOU CHANGE YOUR LONGSTANDING
POLICY TO COME IN LINE WITH OUR
VALUES.
AND I HAD A CONVERSATION, WE HAD
A PRIVATE CONVERSATION WITH UPS
AND SAID, WAIT A MINUTE, WHY ARE
YOU DOING THIS?
THIS IS A LONG-TERM POLICY THAT
THE BOY SCOUTS HAVE HAD.
WHY ARE YOU TAKING YOUR MONEY
AWAY
WE HAVE A RIGHT TO YOU GIVE
MONEY TO THOSE WHO REFLECT OUR
VALUES.
>> THE COMPANY ISN'T INTERESTED
IN TRUE DIVERSITY BUT IN STRONG
ARMING ANYONE WHO DISAGREES WITH
THEIR EXTREME AGENDA, INCLUDING
A CENTURY OLD YOUTH DEVELOPMENT
PROGRAM, WHOSE ONLY CRIME IS
INSTILLING CHARACTER INTO
MILLIONS OF AMERICAN BOYS.
SOME PEOPLE COULD SUGGEST THAT
NOT ALLOWING GAY MEMBERS, HOW
DOES NOT ALLOWING GAY MEMBERS
INSTILL CHARACTER INTO BOYS?
>> LOOK, WHEN YOU LOOK AT WHO
CHARTERS BOY SCOUT TROOPS,
OVER 2/3 ARE CHARTERED BY
CHURCHES, THAT'S WHERE THEY HOST
THEIR MEETINGS, THE VALUES THAT
RUN PARALLEL TO THE BOY SCOUTS.
WHAT HAVE YOU IS YOU HAVE A FEW
CORPORATIONS, MAJOR CORPORATION
WHO'S ARE SAYING, LOOK, UNLESS
YOU ABANDON A CENTURY OLD VALUE
SET, WE'RE NOT GOING TO GIVE YOU
MONEY.
AND THE -- SOME THINGS DON'T
CHANGE WITH TIME.
THE BOY SCOUTS ARE ONE THAT HAVE
LAID DOWN A MARKER AND SAID WE
WILL CONTINUE WITH WHAT'S WORKED
FOR OUR BOYS AND CONTINUE TO
PRODUCE YOUNG MEN WHO MAKE GOOD
CITIZENS.
>> TONY PERKINS, THANK YOU FOR
COMING IN.
APPRECIATE IT.
>>> POLICE IN MALAYSIA HAVE MADE
A DENT IN THE ILLEGAL TRADE OF
ELEPHANT TUSKS.
THEY SEIZED A SHIPMENT WORTH $20
MILLION.
IT WAS HEADED TO CHINA, WHERE
ELEPHANT TUSKS ARE IN HIGH
DEMAND.
POACHERS SLAUGHTER THOUSANDS OF
ELEPHANTS IN ORDER TO GET THE
TUSKS.
>>> SALVATION ARMY WORKERS IN
OKLAHOMA FOUND A WEDDING RING IN
ONE OF THEIR RED KETTLES, BUT
THEY DON'T KNOW IF THE RING IS
REALLY A GENEROUS DONATION OR IF
IT SLIPPED OFF SOMEONE'S FINGER,
SOMEONE COULD BE REALLY UPSET
RIGHT NOW THAT THEY DON'T KNOW
WHERE THE RING IS.
THEY ARE GIVING THE OWNER 90
DAYS TO COME FORWARD.
AFTER THAT IT'S CONSIDERED A
DONATION.
>>> SUFFERING THROUGH A LOSING
SEASON IN THE NFL IS BAD ENOUGH,
BUT BLOCKING YOUR OWN PUNTER'S
KICK?
MORE ON LAST NIGHT'S BIZARRE
PLAY, COMING UP.
>> YOU'RE NOT SUPPOSED TO DO
THAT.
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Incredible 4G LTE
by HTC for $49.99.
I NEED YOU.
I FEEL SO ALONE.
BUT YOU'RE NOT
ALONE.
I KNEW YOU'D COME.
LIKE I COULD STAY AWAY.
YOU KNOW I CAN'T DO THIS
WITHOUT YOU.
YOU'LL NEVER HAVE TO.
YOU'RE ALWAYS THERE
FOR ME.
SHH!
I'LL GET YOU
A RENTAL CAR.
I COULD ALSO USE
AN UMBRELLA.
FALL IN LOVE WITH
PROGRESSIVE'S CLAIMS SERVICE.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
>>> FRIDAY MORNING.
SOLEDAD IS HERE WITH A LOOK
WHAT'S HAPPENING ON "STARTING
POINT."
>> LOTS TO TALK ABOUT.
ESPECIALLY AS THE HOUSE IS
SCHEDULED TO END ITS SESSION
TODAY.
NO DEAL ON THE FISCAL CLIFF,
EVEN IF THE PRESIDENT AND
SPEAKER BAYNE ESPEAK
SPEAKER BOEHNER REACH A DEAL,
WILL IS THERE TIME TO APPROVE IT
BEFORE THE END OF YEAR.
WE'LL TALK TO PHILIP BREDERSON
AND DAN GLICKMAN.
>> A HIGH SCHOOL BASKETBALL
GAME, SCORE 107-2.
A NATIONAL DISCUSSION ABOUT
SPORTSMANSHIP, FAIR PLAY, THE
MERCY RULE.
AT WHAT POINT, TOO MANY POINTS
ON THE BOARD THERE?
SHOULD THE COACHES HAVE CALLED
THE GAME OR JUST LET THE SCORE
GET THAT UNEVEN?
WE'LL TALK TO MEMBERS OF THE
LOSING TEAM AND THEIR COACH
ABOUT THEIR PHILOSOPHY ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENS NEXT, AND WE
VISITED THAT SCHOOL IN
INDIANAPOLIS.
WE'VE HAD A LOT OF CHANGES.
>> DID YOU PLAY BASKETBALL WITH
THEM?
>> I DID NOT.
>>> A NEW MOVIE, CALLED
"ALEDGEANCE."
ABOUT NATIONAL GUARDSMEN WHO
EXPECTED PARTTIME DUTY AND WERE
THROWN INTO YEARS LONG
DEPLOYMENTS IN IRAQ.
>> IT'S FRIDAY.
>> YES, I'M STRUGGLING WITH A
HEAD COLD, REALLY READY FOR A
WEEKEND.
>>> SUSAN RICE TAKING HERSELF
OUT OF THE RUNNING TO BE THE
NEXT SECRETARY OF STATE.
SHE'LL MEET WITH PRESIDENT OBAMA
AT THE WHITE HOUSE, AND A FEW
CRITICIZED RICE OVER STATEMENTS
SHE MADE OVER THE U.S. MISSION
IN BENGHAZI, IT KILLED FOUR
AMERICANS, INCLUDING U.S.
AMBASSADOR TO LIBYA, CHRIS
STEVENS.
>>> CELEBRATIONS BREAKING OUT IN
PYONGYANG OR STAGED, UNCLEAR.
TOASTING WITH BEER MUGS AND
DANCING ON SIDEWALKS AFTER THE
FIRST SUCCESSFUL SATELLITE
LAUNCH INTO SPACE, EVEN THOUGH
THE U.S. SAYS THAT THE NORTH
KOREANS MIGHT NOT HAVE CONTROL
OF THAT IN THE MOMENT.
KIM JUNG UN GOT INTO THE ACT.
THIS PHOTO OF THE LAUNCH, AS
LEADERS CALL FOR PUNISHMENT,
INSISTING THAT NORTH KOREANS
HAVE MOVED A STEP CLOSER TO BE
ABLE TO LAUNCH NUCLEAR WEAPONS
ACROSS THE OCEAN.
>>> EAGLES FUMBLE THE BALL FOUR
TIMES, ONE INTERCEPTION, AND THE
WORST PART OF ALL?
THIS.
THEY HAD A PUNT BLOCKED BY THEIR
OWN PLAYER.
ALL THIS IN A 34-13 LOSS AT
HOME.
EAGLES LOST TO 4-2 AND
CINCINNATI KEPT THEIR PLAYOFF
HOPES ALIVE.
I KNOW ARE YOU NOT A BIG
FOOTBALL FAN, BUT YOU ARE NOT
SUPPOSED TO BLOCK YOUR OWN
PUNTS.
>> I FEEL BAD FOR THAT GUY.
I BET THEY REALLY RAZZED HIM OR
DIDN'T EVEN TALK TO HIM.
>> STORMY WEATHER IN THE
SOUTHWEST.
ROB MARCIANO.
DON'T YOU FEEL BAD FOR HIM?
>> I DON'T THINK I'VE EVER SEEN
ANYTHING LIKE THAT HEY, IT'S THE
EAGLES.
BETTER LUCK NEXT YEAR, GUYS,
WE'LL BE ROOTING FOR YOU, OR AT
LEAST MOST OF US.
>>> THE CHARGERS IN SAN DIEGO,
GOT HEAVY RAIN YESTERDAY, THAT
WE SHOWED YOU LAST HOUR, AND I
THINK I'M GOING TO SHOW IT TO
YOU THIS HOUR, ANYWAY, IT'S WET.
HERE YOU GO.
AND RAIN UP TO THE WHEEL WELLS
OF CARS.
IN SAN DIEGO, THAT'S MORE THAN A
MONTH'S WORTH OF RAIN IT SLOWED
DOWN THIS CAR AND SEVERAL OTHERS
ACROSS PARTS OF SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA.
SAN DIEGO RECORD, 1.5 INCHES.
YUMA NOT A RECORD.
A HALF AN INCH.
THAT'S A LOT.
VEGAS, QUARTER OF AN INCH OF
RAIN.
THAT'S A RECORD, AND YESTERDAY,
THEIR 25th DAY REPORTING
THUNDERSTORMS AROUND LAS VEGAS
AREA, AND THE RECORD IS 26.
RATHER STORMY YEAR FOR THE FOLKS
ALONG THE STRIP THERE.
RAINFALL ACROSS PARTS OF
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA.
RAINING IN PHOENIX, SNOWING
HEAVILY IN FLAGSTAFF, SNOWING AT
THE GRAND CANYON AND PLACES LIKE
THE FOUR CORNERS AND SAN JUANS
OF SOUTHWEST COLORADO.
PROBABLY GET A GOOD DUMPING OUT
OF THERE.
A FOOT OF SNOW EXPECTED IN THE
MOUNTAINS OF NEW MEXICO.
SEVERAL INCHES IF NOT A FOOT OF
SNOW.
AND A PRETTY POTENT ONE.
OUT TO THE PLAINS, PUMP UP THE
HEAT ACROSS THE SOUTHERN PLAINS.
TEMPERATURES WELL ABOVE NORMAL.
EAST OF THE MISSISSIPPI.
TEMPERATURES WHERE THEY SHOULD
BE.
COMFORTABLY CHILLY.
SUNSHINE COMING UP.
SHOULD WARM THINGS UP.
CLEAR NIGHT LAST NIGHT IF YOU
GOT OUT TO SEE THE GEMINID
METEOR SHOWER.
CHICAGO, 49.
NOT TOO BAD TO DO YOUR MID
DECEMBER CHRISTMAS SHOWERS.
>> I SAW THE METEORS BEFORE I
WENT TO BED AND WHEN I WOKE UP.
>> HIS KIDS RAN IN, DAD, DAD,
YOU CAN'T MISS THIS.
>> GOOD STUFF IF YOU COULD BRAVE
THE CHILL.
>> THANK YOU, APPRECIATE IT.
>>> COMING UP, WE'LL INTRODUCE
TO YOU A REMARKABLE YOUNG MAN
USING TALENT TO TURN THE
HEARTACHE OF CANCER INTO AN
INSPIRING LEGACY.
>>> WELCOME BACK.
GOOD MORNING.
A STORY OF A BRAVE YOUNG MAN WHO
LIVES IN MINNESOTA.
ONLY 17 AND NOT EXPECTED TO SEE
18.
>> HE HAS TERMINAL CANCER.
HE'S ACCEPTED HIS FATE, BUT HE'S
LEAVING FOR HIS FAMILY AND
FRIENDS A BEAUTIFUL, MUSICAL
LEGACY.
HERE IS ED LAVENDERA.
>> Reporter: ZACH SOBIAC'S SOUL
IS FILLED WITH LYRICS RACING
AGAINST TIME TO GET OUT.
♪
.
>> Reporter: THREE YEARS AGO,
ZACH WAS DIAGNOSED WITH
OSTEOSARCOMA, A RARE BONE CANCER
THAT TARGETS TEENAGERS, HE HAS
HAD TEN SURGERIES, ENDLESS CHEMO
THERAPY AND MOSTLY BAD NEWS.
ZACH'S DOCTOR HAS TOLD HIM HE
ONLY HAS MONTHS TO LIVE.
HIS MOM SUGGESTED HE START
WRITING GOOD-BYE LETTERS TO
FAMILY AND FRIENDS.
>> I AM AWFUL AT WRITING.
I CAN'T SIT DOWN AND WRITE A
LETTER.
I'VE TRIED.
I DECIDED TO PICK UP MY GUITAR
AND STARTED PLAYING MUSIC.
THIS IS FUN.
>> Reporter: THAT'S HOW HIS SONG
CALLED "CLOUDS" WAS BORN.
A GOOD-BYE TO THOSE HE LOVES.
>> YOU WANT TO LEAVE A MELODY
BEHIND?
>> I DO.
>> Reporter: AND YOU THINK THAT
WILL HELP THEM COPE?
>> IT'S KIND OF ME ALWAYS BEING
THERE FOR THEM.
LIKE IF THEY KEEP SAYING THAT
SONG THROUGHOUT THEIR WHOLE
LIFE, I'LL BE RIGHT NEXT TO THEM
THE WHOLE WAY.
>> Reporter: ZACK CAN'T STOP
WRITING LYRICS, SO MANY SONGS HE
WANTS TO LEAVE BEHIND.
>> YOU HAVE TO LIVE LIFE FAST.
YOU CAN'T REALLY PUT ON THE
BRAKES AT ALL.
I CAN'T WAIT FOR ANYTHING.
AND SO THAT'S KIND OF LIKE ONE
OF THE THINGS WHEN PEOPLE SAY
HOLD ON, WE HAVE TO WAIT FOR
THIS.
I SAY I CAN'T.
LET'S GO.
TOMORROW, WHAT ARE WE DOING?
>> Reporter: ZACK IS 17.
A SENIOR AT STILLWATER HIGH
SCHOOL.
HE GOES TO CLASS, BUT TOLD HIS
TEACHERS, HE WOULDN'T BE DOING
HOMEWORK THIS YEAR.
MAKING TO GRADUATION WOULD BE A
GIFT.
I HAVEN'T SEEN YOU STOP SMILING.
>> IT'S -- WHY NOT?
WHY NOT.
MIGHT AS WELL SMILE.
>> Reporter: ZACK WANTS HIS SONG
"CLOUDS" TO RAISE AWARENESS
ABOUT CHILDHOOD CANCER.
BUT FOR HIS FAMILY, THE LYRICS
ARE A CONSTANT REMINDER THE END
IS NEAR.
>> HE MAKES YOU CRY.
IT'S THE LYRICS AND HAVING HIM
ACTUALLY ARTICULATE IT AND SAY
THIS IS WHAT IT IS AND THIS IS
WHAT I BELIEVE.
IT'S A TOUGH THING TO HEAR FROM
YOUR KID.
>> HE'S LEAVING A LEGACY BEHIND
AND INSPIRING SO MANY PEOPLE,
AND THAT IS MORE THAN ANY OF US
WILL EVER BE ABLE TO DO.
>> Reporter: WHEN YOU LOOK AT
YOUR FRIENDS AND YOUR FAMILY AND
YOUR SISTERS, WHAT DO YOU THINK?
>> IN ALL HONESTY, I'M SORRY FOR
THEM.
BECAUSE I GET TO LEAVE, AND I
DON'T HAVE TO DEAL WITH ANY OF
THIS, BUT THEY HAVE TO KEEP UP
WITH IT AND DEAL WITH IT.
>> Reporter: TURNING THE
HEARTACHE OF CANCER TO
UNFORGIVABLE MELODIES ZACK'S
FINAL WISH ON THE LONG GOOD-BYE.
♪ IT WON'T BE LONG NOW
>> Reporter: ED LAVENDERA, CNN,
LAKEWOOD, MINNESOTA.
>> FEELING LIFE, LIVING LIFE
INTENSELY RIGHT NOW.
>> ONE BRAVE KID.
HIS VIDEOS ON YOUTUBE HAVE
RECEIVED HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS
OF HITS.
LOVELY AND YOU CAN SEE THEM IF
YOU VISIT OUR WEBSITE.
>>> UP NEXT, WE HAVE SOME BEST
ADVICE FROM OLYMPIC GOLD
MEDALIST GABBY DOUGLAS, AND ON
"STARTING POINT" NEW
DEVELOPMENTS ON THE WAR IN
SYRIA.
THE U.S. MAKING A MAJOR NEW
COMMITMENT TO THE REGION.
YEAH.
LET'S GO.
SAMSUNG GALAXY S3 --
OVER FIFTY DOLLARS LESS
THAN BEST BUY!
WOW! FIFTY BUCKS!
YEAH!
THAT'S A PAIR OF SHOES.
SEE FOR YOURSELF IF YOU COULD
SAVE ON THE GIFTS YOU WANT.
WALMART.
SEE FOR YOURSELF IF YOU COULD
SAVE ON THE GIFTS YOU WANT.
WHY THEY HAVE A
RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
TONIGHT OUR GUEST,
THOMAS SARGENT.
NOBEL LAUREATE
IN ECONOMICS,
AND ONE OF THE MOST CITED
ECONOMISTS IN THE WORLD.
PROFESSOR SARGENT,
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT CD RATES WILL
BE IN TWO YEARS?
NO.
IF HE CAN'T, NO ONE CAN.
THAT'S WHY ALLY HAS
A RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
ALLY BANK.
YOUR MONEY NEEDS AN ALLY.
YOU'LL ALSO CARE ABOUT
OUR NEW OFFER.
YOU GET ACCESS TO NURSES WHO
CAN HELP WITH YOUR QUESTIONS.
AND YOUR LOVED ONE CAN GET
EXELON PATCH FREE FOR 30 DAYS.
IF THE DOCTOR FEELS
IT'S RIGHT FOR THEM.
IT CANNOT CHANGE
HOW THE DISEASE PROGRESSES.
HOSPITALIZATION
AND RARELY DEATH
HAVE BEEN REPORTED IN PATIENTS
WHO WORE MORE THAN ONE PATCH
AT A TIME.
THE MOST COMMON SIDE EFFECTS
OF EXELON PATCH
ARE NAUSEA, VOMITING,
AND DIARRHEA.
THE LIKELIHOOD AND SEVERITY
OF THESE SIDE EFFECTS
MAY INCREASE
AS THE DOSE INCREASES.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
LOSS OF APPETITE OR WEIGHT.
PATIENTS WHO WEIGH
LESS THAN 110 POUNDS
MAY EXPERIENCE
MORE SIDE EFFECTS.
PEOPLE AT RISK
FOR STOMACH ULCERS
WHO TAKE CERTAIN
OTHER MEDICINES
SHOULD TALK TO THEIR DOCTOR
BECAUSE SERIOUS
STOMACH PROBLEMS
SUCH AS BLEEDING MAY WORSEN.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
SLOW HEART RATE.
THIRTY DAYS OF EXELON PATCH
FREE FOR YOUR LOVED ONE.
ACCESS TO TRAINED NURSES
FOR YOU.
CALL 1-855-999-1399
OR VISIT EXELONPATCHOFFER2.COM.
TILL YOU FINISH YOUR VEGETABLES.
[ clock ticking ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THERE'S A BETTER WAY...
V8 V-FUSION.
VEGETABLE NUTRITION THEY NEED,
FRUIT TASTE THEY LOVE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
OR...TRY KIDS BOXES!
have led to an increase intands
clinical depression.
Drug and alcohol abuse is up.
And those dealing with grief
don't have access to the
professional help they need.
When you see these issues, do
you want to walk away or
step up?
With a degree in the field of
Counseling or Psychology from
Capella University, you'll have
the knowledge to make
a difference in the lives of
others.
Let's get started at
CAPELLA.EDU
WITH ODOR FREE ASPERCREME.
POWERFUL MEDICINE
RELIEVES PAIN FAST,
WITH NO ODOR.
SO ALL YOU NOTICE IS RELIEF.
ASPERCREME.
WEEKEND FOR MORNING TV.
WE WRAP UP WITH WEST AHEBEST AD.
>> THIS MORNING, GABRIELLE GOING
TO LASS.
>> THE BEST ADVICE WAS DON'T
EVER QUIT, KEEP PUSHING AND
FIGHT LITTLE FOR MY DREAMS.
>> ONE OF THE MOST FEARLESS
COMPETITORS OF THE WORLD, WHEN
WE ASKED HER TO FILM THAT --
>> SHE WAS A LITTLE NERVOUS.
REALLY THOUGHT ABOUT WHAT SHE
WANTED TO SAY, AND SAID NEVER
QUIT.
BUT THERE IS A GIRL WHO ALMOST
QUIT AND CAME BACK AND WON GOLD.
>> I CAN'T IMAGINE HER EVER
BEING NERVOUS.
THAT IS IT FOR "EARLY START."
I'M JOHN BERMAN.
ND