"STARTING POINT" NEXT.
>>> THE U.S. IS DEPLOYING 400
TROOPS, 2 AIR DEFENSE MISSILE
BATTERIES TO DEFEND TURKEY
AGAINST SYRIA.
WE'LL HAVE A LIVE REPORT THIS
MORNING.
>>> AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE TAKES
HERSELF OUT OF THE RUNNING FOR
SECRETARY OF STATE.
WHY DID SHE DO IT?
WHO WILL REPLACE HILLARY
CLINTON?
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA AND JOHN
BOEHNER MEET FOR 50 MINUTES, BUT
DIDN'T WALK OUT WITH A FISCAL
CLIFF DEAL.
BUT THEY DIDN'T REACH A DEAL,
WHAT'S NEXT?
>>> WHY ARE THESE UKRAINIAN
LAWMAKERS THROWING PUNCHES.
GLAD WE'RE NOT THERE.
>> NOT THERE YET.
FRIDAY, DECEMBER 14th.
"STARTING POINT" BEGINS NOW.
GOOD MORNING, EVERYBODY.
OUR STARTING POINT, A DEVELOPING
STORY ABOUT SYRIA'S ONGOING
CIVIL WAR AND A NEW ROLE FOR THE
UNITED STATES.
LEON PANETTA SIGNED AN ORDER TO
SEND TWO PATRIOT MISSILE
BATTERIES TO TURKEY ALONG WITH
400 U.S. TROOPS TO HELP THE
COUNTRY DEFEND AGAINST ANY U.S.
ACTION BY SYRIA.
THE MOVE WAS EXPECTED AS THE
REBELLION DESTABILIZES OR BEGINS
TO DESTABILIZE THE ASSAD REGIME.
NICK PATON WALSH HAS THE LATEST
FOR US.
NICK, GOOD MORNING.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING.
400 U.S. TROOPS EXPECTED TO BE
ON THE GROUND, BUT THIS
CONTRIBUTION OF THREE TOTAL
MEMBER NATIONS, GERMANY EXPECTED
TO BEGIN RATIFYING ITS
DEPLOYMENT OF TWO PATRIOT
BATTERIES, THE NETHERLANDS AS
WELL.
LET ME GIVE YOU THE BACK STORY.
THE PAST TWO MONTHS WE HAVE SEEN
EXCHANGES, SYRIAN ARMY ACCUSED
OF FIRING INTO TURKEY.
TURKEY RETURNING FIRE.
THAT SENSE OF HOST TILLITY AND
VOLATILITY ON THE BORDER LEADING
THEM TO ASK NATO FOR HELP AND
PATRIOTS COMING HERE AT THIS
POINT.
EXPECTED TO BE USED MOSTLY IN
THE EVENT OF MISSILES BEING
FIRED AND HAVE THE ABILITY TO
TAKE DOWN AIRCRAFT AS WELL.
WE HEARD FROM U.S. SECRETARY OF
DEFENSE LEON PANETTA, THAT THE
U.S. DOES HAVE A PLAN IN THE
EVENT THAT THEY SEE THE ASSAD
REGIME USE OR PREPARE TO USE
CHEMICAL WEAPONS.
NOT CLEAR IF PATRIOTS WILL BE
INVOLVED IN THAT.
BUT RIGHT NOW, IN THE VERY
VOLATILE PART OF THE WORLD, WE
HAVE U.S. TROOPS POTENTIALLY ON
THE GROUND.
>> NICK PATON WALSH, THANK YOU
FOR THE UPDATE.
>>> FRANK DISCUSSIONS, OPEN
LINES OF COMMUNICATION, BUT NO
DEAL.
18 DAYS UNTIL THE FISCAL CLIFF.
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND JOHN BOEHNER
MET JUST UNDER AN HOUR.
AFTER COORDINATED PRESS
RELEASES, BOTH SIDES ASSURED THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE THAT
COMMUNICATION LINES REMAIN OPEN.
DANA BASH IS LIVE IN WASHINGTON,
D.C. THIS MORNING.
50 MINUTES AND SORT OF A VERY
MILQUETOASTY KIND OF STATEMENT
AT THE END OF IT, SOUNDS NOT
GOOD.
>> NO, NOT GOOD, CONSIDERING
WHERE WE ARE IN THE CALENDACALE.
I'M TOLD BY SOURCES IN BOTH
PARTIES, A MEETING THAT DID NOT
PRODUCE ANY NEW IDEAS, MORE OF
TOUCHING BASE MEETING, THE
PRESIDENT WANTED TO TALK TO THE
SPEAKER BEFORE HE WENT HOME TO
OHIO, WHICH HE STILL PLANNED TO
DO THIS WEEKEND, THE SOURCES SAY
THAT THE BASIC PROBLEM STILL IS,
SOLEDAD, AFTER ALL OF THE WEEKS,
IS DEMOCRATS STILL BELIEVE
REPUBLICANS HAVE THE PROBLEM.
THEY NEED TO DEAL WITH THE DEBT
CRISIS BY RAISING MORE REVENUE,
MEANING RAISING MORE TAXES AND
REPUBLICANS STILL THINK
DEMOCRATS ARE THE PROBLEM.
THEY ARE NOT OFFERING ENOUGH IN
SPENDING CUTS.
THE ISSUE IS, REALITY,
DEMOCRATS, THE PRESIDENT HAS THE
MOST LEVERAGE.
HAS HAD THE MOST LEVERAGE,
REPUBLICANS KNOW THAT.
EVERYBODY SEE WHERE IS THIS WILL
PROBABLY GO.
REPUBLICANS HAVE TO GIVE SOME ON
THE RATE INCREASES FOR THE MOST
WEALTHY.
AND THE QUESTION, WHEN IS IT
MOST POLITICALLY ADVANTAGEOUS
FOR BOTH SIDES TO AGREE TO THAT.
>> LET ME ASK A QUESTION.
YOU HAVE HAD A CHANCE TO TALK TO
TWO FORMER MAJORITY LEADERS FROM
OPPOSITE SIDES OF THE AISLE WHAT
ARE THEY SAYING ABOUT WHERE WE
ARE AND THE FACT THAT THERE WILL
BE A DEAL SOMEWHERE SOON?
>> TRENT LOTT AND TOM DASCHLE,
REPUBLICAN AND DEMOCRATIC
LEADER, OPPOSITE SIDES OF THE
TABLE FOUR YEARS, WORKING
TOGETHER ON TOUGH ISSUES AND
THEY POINTED OUT IT IS CERTAINLY
POSSIBLE, OF COURSE IT IS
POSSIBLE.
THEY HAVE TO HAVE THE POLITICAL
WILL IN TO THE POLITICAL LEADERS
AND THEY POINTED OUT THAT TIMING
ON A DEAL IS REALLY KEY.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> VERY TRUE.
>>> THE SPEAKER IS GOING TO HAVE
TO MAKE A DECISION ON THAT, AND
THE PRESIDENT IS GOING TO HAVE
TO MAKE A DECISION ON WHAT HE
WILL DO IN RETURN ON SPENDING,
AND THEY NEED TO DO IT ON
CONCERT.
YOU HAVE TO HAVE THE WINDS AND
THE BRASS COME TOGETHER.
>> MAYBE HOLD HANDS AND JUMP OFF
THE CLIFF TOGETHER?
>> IT WOULD BE MORE FUN ON THE
WAY DOWN.
AT LEAST HAVE YOU COMPANY.
>> WHETHER OR NOT THAT IS ALL
GOING TO HAPPEN BEFORE THE ENDS
OF THE YEAR, REALLY STILL IS AN
OPEN QUESTION.
BUT, SOLEDAD, OUTSIDE A MEETING
OF REPUBLICANS YESTERDAY, AND
ALL OF THEM SAID THAT THE
SPEAKER TOLD THEM, DON'T MAKE
CHRISTMAS PLANS.
>> YEAH, NOT A SHOCK EITHER.
AND I THINK JUMPING OFF A CLIFF,
WHETHER YOU HAVE HANDS TO HOLD
OR NO HANDS TO HOLD IS ALL BAD,
ALL THE WAY DOWN.
DANA BASH THIS MORNING,
APPRECIATE IT.
>>> DIPLOMATIC SHOCKER TO UPDATE
YOU ON AFTER THE REPUBLICAN
FIRESTORM ON THE ATTACK IN
BENGHAZI, SUSAN RICE HAS TAKEN
HERSELF OUT OF THE RUNNING,
WON'T TRY TO SUCCEED SECRETARY
OF STATE HILLARY CLINTON FOR
THAT ROLE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA TALKED ABOUT
AMBASSADOR RICE'S DECISION LAST
NIGHT.
>> I HADN'T MADE A DECISION
ABOUT WHO WOULD BE MY NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE.
NO DOUBT, SUSAN IS QUALIFIED.
OTHER PEOPLE ARE QUALIFIED AS
WELL.
HER INTEREST IS IN SERVING ME,
BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY, IN SERVING
THE COUNTRY.
COULD NOT BE PROUDER OF HER.
SHE IS ONE OF THE TOP MEMBERS OF
MY NATIONAL SECURITY TEAM.
>> SHE'LL MEET WITH THE
PRESIDENT TODAY, OUR FOREIGN
AFFAIRS REPORTER, ELISE LABOTT
IN WASHINGTON, D.C.
BREAK THIS DOWN WHAT'S HAPPENING
BEHIND THE SCENES.
SHE SAID IN HER RESIGNATION NOTE
THAT SHE'S DECIDED TO DO THIS
FOR THE GOOD OF THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE, SO THERE IS NOT THIS
CONTENTIOUS, PARTISAN DEBATE.
WHAT'S REALLY HAPPENING HERE?
>> WELL, I'VE TALKED TO SOME OF
OUR AIDES.
SHE WAS READY FOR A FIGHT.
SHE DOESN'T GIVE UP ON A FIGHT.
TWEETED THIS MORNING WITH AN
OP-ED IN "THE WASHINGTON POST,"
BUT OVER THE LAST COUPLE OF DAYS
AND WEEKS, HER AIDES AND SHE
STARTED TO DO THE MATH.
WASN'T JUST ABOUT BENGHAZI
ANYMORE, MORPHED INTO SOMETHING
ELSE, ON OTHER ISSUES BACK WHEN
SHE WAS IN THE CLINTON
ADMINISTRATION, INCREASINGLY
POLITICIZED AND WASN'T GOING TO
STOP.
SO SHE MADE THE TOUGH DECISION
AND ALSO I THINK, SOLEDAD, HER
AIDES FELT THAT THIS DETRACTED
FROM SOME OF THE MORE SUCCESSFUL
WORK THAT SHE DID AS U.S.
AMBASSADOR TO THE UNITED
NATIONS.
IF YOU REMEMBER, SHE WAS
INSTRUMENTAL IN PASSING THE
TOUGHEST SANCTIONS EVER ON IRAN.
PUSHED FOR MILITARY ACTION IN
LIBYA AND OTHER THINGS.
TAKE A LISTEN TO WHAT SHE TOLD
NBC NEWS ABOUT WHY SHE WITHDRAW
H
HER NAME.
>> I DIDN'T WANT TO SEE A
CONFIRMATION PROCESS THAT WAS
VERY PROLONGED, VERY
POLITICIZED, VERY DISTRACTING
AND VERY DISRUPTIVE.
BECAUSE THERE ARE SO MANY THINGS
WE NEED TO GET DONE AS A
COUNTRY.
>> AND, SOLEDAD, SHE HAS A LOT
OF WORK TO DO AT THE U.N.
RIGHT NOW, THE U.S. IS TRYING TO
GET A RESOLUTION IMPOSING
SANCTIONS ON NORTH KOREA THE
SYRIA CRISIS, AND RIGHT NOW, THE
SHORT LIST FOR SECRETARY
CLINTON'S REPLACEMENT, DOWN TO
ONE MAN, SENATOR JOHN KERRY, WHO
IS SEEN AS SOMEONE WHO HAS A
LOCALITY OF WORLD STATURE, A LOT
OF RELATIONSHIPS WITH WORLD
LEADERS AND CERTAINLY AS
CHAIRMAN OF THE SENATE FOREIGN
RELATIONS COMMITTEE HAS A LOT OF
FOREIGN POLICY CHOPS AND MOST
ATTRACTIVE TO THE
ADMINISTRATION, SOLEDAD, HE'S
HE'S I WILL CONFIRMABLE.
>> ELISE LABOTT, THANK YOU.
THAT'S A VERY SHORT LIST.
ONE NAME ON IT.
>> SHORT LIST OF ONE.
>>> LIVE PICTURES OF A PRO
PRESIDENT MOHAMED MORSI RALLY IN
CAIRO.
SHE A
MEMBERS OF THE OPPOSITION SAY
THE CONSTITUTION IS TOO ISLAMIST
AND INFRINGES ON MINORITY
RIGHTS.
PROTESTING OUTSIDE THE
PRESIDENTIAL PALACE RIGHT NOW.
>>> NEW THIS MORNING, A 6.4
MAGNITUDE EARTHQUAKE OFF THE
COAST OF BAJA.
SO FAR, NO TSUNAMI WARNINGS.
>>> CLACKAMAS TOWN CENTER WILL
REOPEN TO SHOPPERS IN SIX HOURS.
THAT'S THE MALL WHERE A GUNMAN
KILLED TWO PEOPLE ON TUESDAY AND
CRITICALLY WOUNDED A THIRD
BEFORE KILLING HIMSELF.
A CANDLE-LIGHT VIGIL WILL BE
HELD OUTSIDE THE MALL.
>>> A FUNERAL FOR FALLEN DALLAS
COWBOYS PLAYER JERRY BROWN.
BROWN WAS KILLED IN A SUSPECTED
DRUNK DRIVING ACCIDENT ON
SATURDAY.
HIS TEAMMATE AND FRIEND JOSH
BRENT WAS BEHIND THE WHEEL.
YOU ARE LOOKING AT NEW DASHCAM
VIDEO OF THE WRECK RELEASED BY
POLICE ALONG WITH 911 CALLS THEY
RECEIVED IN MOMENTS AFTER THE
ACCIDENT.
>> IS ANYBODY INJURED?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
I JUST DROVE PAST IT.
LOOKS LIKE IT JUST HAPPENED.
A CAR UPSIDE DOWN.
>> JOSH BRENT IS FREE ON HALF A
MILLION DOLLARS BAIL.
HE'S CHARGED WITH INTOXICATION
MANSLAUGHTER.
>>> SO TODAY IS THE DEADLINE FOR
STATES TO DECLARE WHETHER THEY
WILL SET UP THEIR OWN HEALTH
INSURANCE EXCHANGES.
22 STATES WILL NOT DO IT.
IN THOSE CASES, THE AFFORDABLE
CARE ACT DICTATES THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT COMES IN AND WILL DO
IT FOR THEM.
THE EXCHANGES WILL OFFER
CONSUMERS AN INTERNET BASED
MARKETPLACE FOR PURCHASING
PRIVATE HEALTH INSURANCE PLANS.
SO IT HASN'T COME TO THIS IN
WASHINGTON, D.C., YET.
THIS BRAWL BROKE OUT ON THE
FLOOR OF UKRAINE'S PARLIAMENT.
LOTS OF PUSHING, SHOVING, COLLAR
GRABBING, AND THE SCUFFLE
APPARENTLY STARTED AFTER MEMBERS
OF UKRAINE'S OPPOSITION PARTY
ACCUSED TWO OF THEIR OWN MEMBERS
OF PLANNING TO DEFECT TO THE
RULING PARTY.
I GUESS THE GOOD NEWS, IT'S NOT
PARTISANSHIP, IT'S FIGHTING
WITHIN THE PARTY.
YOU KNOW, LOOKING FOR A SILVER
LINING.
>> THEY ARE TALKING.
NOT JUST SAYING WE HAD FRANK
DISCUSSIONS.
>> THOSE ARE MORE THAN FRANK
DISCUSSIONS RIGHT THERE.
>> CAN YOU IMAGINE IF WE HAD
VIDEO FISCAL CLIFF COME TO THIS
AND PEOPLE GOING AT EACH OTHER.
NO WOMEN AT THIS SHOT.
I LOOKED VERY CLOSELY.
WHAT DOES THAT SAY?
>> SORRY BERMAN.
>>> AHEAD ON "STARTING POINT"
THIS MORNING, "BLACK IN AMERICA"
WILL REAIR ON SATURDAY.
AND AN ESPN HOST IS QUESTIONING
THE BLACKNESS OF A STAR FOOTBALL
PLAYER ROBERT GRIFFIN III, RG3
ON AIR, WHAT WAS SAID AND THE
FALLOUT FROM THAT, STRAIGHT
AHEAD.
PLUS, BUSINESS NEWS.
ONE MORE WAY THE FISCAL CLIFF
COULD COST YOU.
WHAT HAPPENS TO YOUR PAYCHECK
IMMEDIATELY IF THERE IS NO DEAL
IN WASHINGTON?
THAT'S NEXT.
Bring it down, please?
Better. That's what happens to
background noise,
when you're making
a call on this.
This microphone here, picks up
the sounds around you and helps
turn them down.
So when the world gets noisy
Calls sound better.
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
YOU WANNA SEE IF WALMART HAS
SIMILAR GIFTS FOR LESS?
YEAH.
LET'S GO.
SAMSUNG GALAXY S3 --
OVER FIFTY DOLLARS LESS
THAN BEST BUY!
WOW! FIFTY BUCKS!
YEAH!
THAT'S A PAIR OF SHOES.
SEE FOR YOURSELF IF YOU COULD
SAVE ON THE GIFTS YOU WANT.
WALMART.
Aunt Sally's
singing again.
It's a tradition,
honey.
[ singing
Christmas carols ]
mmmm.
[ Female Announcer ]
Make new traditions
with Pillsbury Grands!
Cinnamon Rolls.
[ Female Announcer ]
Make new traditions
ONE IS FOR A CLEAN,
WEDOMESTIC ENERGY FUTURE
THAT PUTS US IN CONTROL.
OUR ABUNDANT NATURAL GAS
IS ALREADY SAVING US MONEY,
PRODUCING CLEANER ELECTRICITY,
PUTTING US TO WORK
HERE IN AMERICA
AND SUPPORTING WIND AND SOLAR.
THOUGH ALL ENERGY DEVELOPMENT
COMES WITH SOME RISK,
WE'RE COMMITTED TO SAFELY
AND RESPONSIBLY
PRODUCING NATURAL GAS.
IT'S NOT A DREAM.
AMERICA'S NATURAL GAS...
PUTTING US IN CONTROL
OF OUR ENERGY FUTURE, NOW.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO "STARTING
POINT."
I'M CHRISTINE ROMANS, MINDING
YOUR BUSINESS.
THE S & P 500 SNAPPED A SIX-DAY
WINNING STREAK, DESPITE MODELLY
UPBEAT ECONOMIC DATA.
CALL IT THE PAYROLL TAX CLIFF.
OF ALL THE TAX ISSUES BEING
NEGOTIATED IN WASHINGTON, THERE
IS ONE THAT MANY MIDDLE CLASS
FAMILIES WOULD CERTAINLY FEEL
IMMEDIATELY.
THE PAYROLL TAX HOLIDAY THAT
COMES DIRECTLY FROM YOUR
PAYCHECK.
PAYROLL TAXES FUND SOCIAL
SECURITY.
WORKERS HAVE BEEN GETTING A
BREAK.
PAYING A RATE OF 4.2%.
IN 2013, THE RATE IS SAID TO GO
BACK UP TO 6.2%, OF EVERYTHING
YOU MAKE.
TAKE A LOOK AT THIS SOMEONE
MAKING $50,000 A YEAR WILL SEE
$19 LESS IN THEIR TAKE HOME PAY
PER WEEK, STARTING AT THE
BEGINNING OF THE YEAR.
THE PAYROLL TAX CUT, A PIECE OF
THE WHOLE TAX MESS, TAX PUZZLE,
COULD HAVE A DIRECT AFFECT ON
YOUR PAYCHECK.
I'LL TELL UP THE STOCK MARKET UP
13% THIS YEAR.
UNTIL NOW, EVERYBODY SAYS
THEY'LL GET IT SORTED OUT.
I'M STARTING TO GET E-MAILS FROM
STRATEGIES WHO ARE STARTING TO
GET NERVOUS AGAIN.
>> THE STOCK MARKET, GOING UP
BASED ON THAT THIS IS ALL
BLUSTER, BUT NOW YOU THINK IT
WILL START GOING DOWN?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
GREG VALIER, DOES A NOTE TO
CLIENTS, THE FINANCIAL MARKETS
THINK THIS WILL GET SOLVED, BUT
THE WORD AND MOOD IN WASHINGTON
IS IT WON'T.
>> LET'S BRING IN A FORMER
DEMOCRATIC GOVERNOR OF
TENNESSEE.
A MEMBER OF THE CAMPAIGN TO FIX
THE DEBT.
HE JOINS US THIS MORNING.
NICE TO HAVE YOU WITH US, SIR.
GREAT TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
A DOCUMENTARY A COUPLE YEARS
AGO.
>> I REMEMBER.
>> NICE TO HAVE YOU WITH US
TODAY.
I WANT TO TALK -- CHRISTINE,
STICK AROUND.
I WANT TO TALK ABOUT FINANCE
101.
THE DEFICIT IS THE GAP BETWEEN
THE SPENDING AND REVENUE THAT
THE GOVERNMENT HAS EVERY SINGLE
YEAR.
THE CBO IS REPORTING THAT THE
DEFICIT IN 2012 IS A 1$1.1
TRILLION WHICH SOUNDS TERRIBLE,
BUT IT'S ALSO GONE DOWN OVER THE
YEARS, IF YOU LOOK AT 2009, 1.4
TRILLION, 2010, IT DROPPED, 2011
IT DROPPED AND 2012 IT DROPPED.
WHY ARE YOU FOCUSED ON FIXING
THE DEBT AT A TIME WHEN WE VEAL
HAVE A LOW BORROWING RATE?
WHY FOCUS ON FIXING THE DEBT
INSTEAD OF THE DEFICIT?
>> THE TWO OF THEM ARE REALLY
THE SAME THING.
YOU HAVE TO FIX THE DEFICIT IN
ORDER TO GET TO A MORE SENSIBLE
PLACE WITH THE DEBT.
THE DIFFERENCE NOW, WE HAVE
THESE HIGH LEVELS OF DEFICIT IN
THE PAST.
AND THEY CAN'T -- THE WAR -- THE
DEPRESSION WAS OVER.
THE SEPARATION WE'RE IN NOW,
WITH THE DEFICIT BEING DRIVEN BY
AN UNWILLINGNESS NO TAX AND TO
CUT ENTITLEMENTS, NO END IN
SITE.
SOMETHING THAT, YOU KNOW,
THREATENS TO UNDERMINE THE
FINANCIAL STABILITY OF THE
COUNTRY.
A SILLY PLACE FOR TO US BE.
IT'S CRAZY.
>> THREE PILLARS OF FIX THE
DEBT.
WALK US THROUGH.
>> I THINK WE WERE TALKING ABOUT
FIRST OF ALL DOING SOMETHING --
DOING SOMETHING REAL ABOUT IT.
MAKING SURE THAT AT LEAST 4
TRILLION IN REDUCTION OVER THE
COURSE OF THE NEXT TEN YEARS AND
DOING IT IN A SMART WAY, NOT
WALKING OFF THE CLIFF, AND
CAUSING US REALLY TO QUITE
LIKELY MOVE BACK INTO RECESSION.
PLAN IT OUT OVER A PERIOD OF
TIME LIKE INTELLIGENT ADULTS
OUGHT TO DO.
IT HAS TO BE FAIR, THERE HAS TO
BE ENTITLEMENT REFORMS AND
REVENUE INCREASES.
WE NEED TO STOP THIS POLITICAL
WRANGLING THAT JUST LOOKS SO
SILLY OUT HERE IN THE COUNTRY.
THIS IS A SELF-INFLECTED WOUND.
THE FISCAL CLIFF WE'RE LOOKING
AT.
WE NEED TO GET BEYOND THAT AND
GET TO THE REAL PROBLEM, SHOWING
THE WORLD WE KNOW HOW TO RUN THE
GOVERNMENT OF THE UNITED STATES.
>> PAUL KRUGMAN IN "THE NEW YORK
TIMES" HAS AN INTERESTING OP-ED
AND STARTS OFF BY SAYING WE ARE
NOT HAVING A DEBT CRISIS AND
SAYS THIS IS REALLY A POLITICAL
CRISIS.
LET ME READ A BIT OF IT.
AMERICANS MAY NOD THEIR HEADS
WHEN YOU ATTACK BIG GOVERNMENT
IN THE ABSTRACT, BUT THEY
STRONGLY SUPPORT SOCIAL
SECURITY, MEDICARE AND EVEN
MEDICAID.
AND HE'S TALKING ABOUT HIS
FRAMING OF THE GOP.
PART OF THE PROBLEM, AMERICANS
HAVE A SENSE AGAINST BIG
GOVERNMENT, BUT WHEN IT COMES TO
BIG GOVERNMENT, PEOPLE DON'T
WANT TO CUT THOSE THINGS OF WHAT
THEY THINK ARE PART OF WHAT
AMERICANS DESERVE TO HAVE.
>> I PUT THE BLAME ON THAT
SQUARELY ON THE POLITICAL
LEADERSHIP IN WASHINGTON.
I THINK THE COUNTRY IS HUNGRY
AND WOULD RESPONSE TO SOMEONE
HOW YOU FIX THE WHOLE PROBLEM.
THESE ARE THE PIECES THAT YOU
NEED TO PUT TOGETHER TO GET US
OUT OF THIS MESS.
INSTEAD, FOCUSED ON ASPECTS OF
THE THING, AND ABOUT WHETHER
MARGINAL TAX RATES SHOULD GO UP
OR NOT, AND WHAT OUGHT TO BE
DONE ABOUT ENTITLEMENTS IN THE
SHORT TERM.
PEOPLE RESPOND AND WILL RESPOND
IN THIS COUNTRY, ALWAYS HAVE
RESPONDED TO SOMEONE WHO
HONESTLY TELLS THEM WHAT THE
SITUATION IS AND HAS A REAL
PROPOSAL, NOT POLITICAL IN
NATURE.
SHARED SACRIFICE THAT SOLVES THE
PROBLEM.
WE OUGHT TO TRY THAT.
>>> DAVE WELS OF "THE WALL
STREET JOURNAL" WRITES ABOUT THE
RISK OF CUTTING THE DEFICIT, TOO
MUCH TOO SOON.
IF YOU JUST FOCUSED ON JOBS AND
COULD REALLY SOLVE THE PROBLEM,
BRING YOUR DEFICIT TO ZERO.
IF YOU HAD A ROBUST JOB MARKET.
BRING UNEMPLOYMENT DOWN LOW
ENOUGH IN THE BUDGET GEEKS THEIR
VANA CRITICALLY ADJUSTED DEFICIT
SHOULD BE CLOSE TO ZERO WHEN THE
ECONOMY FIRES ON ALL CYLINDERS.
HE IS LIKE DON'T WORRY ABOUT
DEBT, DON'T WORRY ABOUT THE
DEFICIT, WORRY ABOUT JOBS.
>> I DIDN'T READ THAT PIECE, BUT
I DON'T THINK ANYONE BELIEVES
YOU CAN SIMPLY GROW YOUR WAY OUT
OF THIS.
WOULD YOU HAVE TO HAVE GROWTH
RATES IN THE ECONOMY THAT ARE
BEYOND ANYTHING WE'VE
EXPERIENCED OVER A SUSTAINED
PERIOD OF TIME FOR LONG PERIOD
OF TIME TO GROW OUR WAY OUT OF
IT.
THAT'S AN EASY WAY OUT.
THIS REQUIRES TAKING SOME HARD
ACTIONS, AND I THINK EVERYONE
ALSO AGREES WE SHOULDN'T GO OFF
THE CLIFF.
WE ARE IN THE THROES OF A VERY
SORT OF FRAGILE RECOVERY RIGHT
NOW.
LET'S DO THE STUFF IT TAKES,
SPACE IT IN OVER TIME LIKE A
WELL-RUN ORGANIZATION WOULD DO
AND GIVE THE WORLD SOME
CONFIDENCE.
I WOULD MAKE THE POINT IF WE
REALLY SOLVED THIS PROBLEM, IT
WOULD BE A STIMULUS PACKAGE TO
THE ECONOMY GREATER THAN
ANYTHING WE TRIED TO DO BEFORE.
$2 TRILLION SITTING IN CORPORATE
AMERICA SITTING ON THE
SIDELINES.
A LOT OF JOBS, A LOT OF
INVESTMENT.
IF WE CAN PRESENT THEM AND THE
REST OF THE WORLD WITH A STABLE
SITUATION AND AN UNDERSTANDABLE
SITUATION WHERE THERE IS NOT BIG
THINGS IN THE ROAD DOWN THE
ROAD, YOU WILL START TO SEE
MONEY COME IN, AND A HUGE
STIMULUS TO THE ECONOMY.
>> FORMER GOVERNOR, FILL
BRESENEN, THANK YOU.
>> THANKS, ENJOYED.
>>> STILL AHEAD, WE'LL TALK
ABOUT BLACKNESS.
COMMENTS FROM AN ESPN HOST
TALKING ABOUT WASHINGTON
REDSKINS QUARTERBACK RG3.
IT'S -- IT'S SO CRAZY THAT I
CAN'T EVEN SUMMARIZE IT IN A
LINE.
BUT IT -- IT IS A VERY
INTERESTING, AND WE'LL TALK
ABOUT IT ON THE OTHER SIDE OF
THE SHORT BREAK.
WE'RE BACK IN JUST A MOMENT.
look in the mirror,    Sus
they see more than themselves.
So we celebrate our year-end
with the "share the love" event.
Get a great deal on a new Subaru
and 250 dollars goes to your
choice of five charities.
By the end of this, our fifth
year,
our total can reach almost 25
million dollars.
It's a nice reflection on us
all.
Now through January 2nd.
SINCE AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL
WAS FOUNDED BACK IN 1894,
THEY'VE BEEN COMMITTED
TO PUTTING CLIENTS FIRST.
HELPING GENERATIONS
THROUGH TOUGH TIMES.
GOOD TIMES.
NEVER TAKING A BAILOUT.
THERE WHEN YOU NEED THEM.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
OVER THE CENTURIES.
THE STRENGTH OF
A GLOBAL FINANCIAL LEADER.
THE HEART OF
A ONE-TO-ONE RELATIONSHIP.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
Your soups are
so awesomely delicious
my husband and I
can't stop eating 'em!
What's...that...
on your head?
Can curlers!
Tomato basil.
Potato with bacon.
We've got
a lotta empty cans.
[ Male Announcer ] Hear from
our chefs on Facebook
this Friday!
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
OUR TEAM THIS MORNING.
BASTIAN JUNGER, AUTHOR OF A NEW
E-BOOK, CALLED "A WORLD MADE OF
BLOOD."
WE'LL TALK ABOUT THAT LATER.
WILL CANE, CNN CONTRIBUTOR,
COLUMNIST FOR THEBLAZE.COM.
AND WE HAVE A FORMER ADVISER TO
PRESIDENT CLINTON AND A WRITER.
>> HOW ARE YOU?
>> I'M STRUGGLING THIS MORNING.
>> IT'S FRIDAY.
>> I'LL TRY TO FAKE IT.
DID YOU WATCH THE
PARKER.
>> HE MADE YOU WATCH IT.
BECAUSE WE'LL BE TALKING ABOUT
IT.
>> HE'S NOW REALLY DEALING WITH
THIS CONTROVERSIAL ISSUE ABOUT
RACE.
TALKING ABOUT THE WASHINGTON
REDSKINS QUARTERBACK, ROBERT
GRIFFIN III, AND EARLIER IN THE
WEEK, RG3 TOLD A RECORDER HE
WANTS TO BE DEFINED BY HIS WORK
ETHIC AND CHARACTER AND LESS
ABOUT RACE AND THAT PROMPTED
PARKER TO WONDER WHAT KIND OF
BROTHER RG3 REALLY IS.
LET'S PLAY A CHUNK OF THAT.
>> MY QUESTION, WHICH IS JUST A
STRAIGHT, HONEST QUESTION.
IS HE A BROTHER?
OR IS HE A CALL BALL BROTHER?
>> WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
>> HE'S NOT REAL.
HE'S BLACK, BUT HE'S NOT REALLY
DOWN WITH THE CAUSE.
WE ALL KNOW HIS WIFE BEYONCE,
AND HE'S A REPUBLICAN.
NO INFORMATION AT ALL.
I'M TRYING TO DIG DEEPER INTO
WHY HE HAS AN ISSUE.
>> LET ME SAY THIS.
I'M UNCOMFORTABLE WITH WHERE WE
JUST WENT.
>> I LOVE -- I LOVE STEPHEN A.
SMITH.
I'M UNCOMFORTABLE WHERE YOU JUST
WENT.
OUR DOCUMENTARY, "BLACK IN
AMERICA," WHAT IT WAS ALL ABOUT.
RG3 DOESN'T FIT INTO PARKER'S
SENSE OF WHAT REAL BLACKNESS IS.
>> LIKE A STEREOTYPE.
PEOPLE ADVOCATING AGAINST
STEREOTYPES, STEREOTYPING
THEMSELVES THEIR OWN PEOPLE.
>> IT'S SO -- IT'S SO OFFENSIVE
ON SO MANY LEVELS.
YOU LINED UP THREE WHITE GUYS TO
TALK ABOUT THIS THING, THIS TERM
CORNBALL BROTHER, AND I TOOKED
AN INFORMAL POLL, AND ALL MY
BLACK FRIENDS.
HAVE YOU EVER HEARD THE TERM,
THE ANSWER IS UNANIMOUSLY BY THE
WAY NO.
IT TURNED ROBERT GRIFFIN III,
ANY SENSE OF INDIVIDUALITY, AND
HE WANTS TO BE DEFINED BY WHO I
AM, WHICH IS A GREAT AFRIFRICKI
QUARTERBACK.
>> HE FEELS LIKE HE'S DODGING
THE QUESTION.
ARE YOU -- WHAT IS THE ROLE OF
RACE IN BEING THIS GREAT
QUARTERBACK?
RIGHT?
AND FOR PEOPLE OF COLOR, IT'S
OFTEN A CHALLENGE.
HE WANTS TO SAY I DON'T WANT TO
BE DEFINED BY BEING THE BLACK
QUARTERBACK, BUT AT THE SAME
TIME I WANT TO REPRESENT ALL OF
THE BLACK PEOPLE WHO LOOK AT ME
AS A GREAT QUARTERBACK.
MR. PARKER TOOK SOME GREAT
EXCEPTION TO THAT, WHICH IS SORT
OF A PR EFFORT AND --
>> HE IS TRYING TO TAKE
SOMETHING AWAY FROM RG3.
THAT IS THE TONE OF THE
CONVERSATION.
>> IS HE BLACK?
HE HAS THE CORN ROWS.
THAT COLUMN THERE.
BUT HE HAS A WHITE FIANCEE.
BUT HE MIGHT BE WITH THE GOP.
>> MIGHT BE REPUBLICAN.
>> STEPHEN SMITH, NEVER THOUGHT
IN MY WHOLE LIFE HE WOULD BE
UNCOMFORTABLE.
WHO IS BLACK IN AMERICA, MY
DOCUMENTARY, WILL REAIR SATURDAY
AT 8:00 P.M.
AND PARKER, MAYBE I'LL SEND HIM
A COPY OF IT.
>>> STILL AHEAD ON "STARTING
POINT," GENERATING LOTS OF BUZZ,
BUT PEOPLE SAY ZERO DARK 30 GOES
TOO FAR INTO THE HUNT OF OSAMA
BIN LADEN.
WE'LL TELL YOU ABOUT THAT
STRAIGHT AHEAD.
NT.
NOBEL LAUREATE
IN ECONOMICS,
AND ONE OF THE MOST CITED
ECONOMISTS IN THE WORLD.
PROFESSOR SARGENT,
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT CD RATES WILL
BE IN TWO YEARS?
NO.
IF HE CAN'T, NO ONE CAN.
THAT'S WHY ALLY HAS
A RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
ALLY BANK.
YOUR MONEY NEEDS AN ALLY.
but with ADVAIR,
I'm breathing better.
So now I can be in
the scene.
ADVAIR is
clinically proven to help
significantly improve
lung function.
Unlike most COPD medications,
ADVAIR contains both an
anti-inflammatory
and a
long-acting bronchodilator
working together to help improve
your lung function all day.
ADVAIR won't
replace fast-acting inhalers
for sudden symptoms
and should not be used more
than twice a day.
People with
COPD taking ADVAIR
may have a higher chance
of pneumonia.
ADVAIR may increase your
risk of osteoporosis
and some eye problems.
Tell your doctor
if you have a heart condition
or high blood pressure before
taking ADVAIR.
If you're still
having difficulty breathing,
ask your doctor if including
ADVAIR could help
improve your lung function.
Get your
first full
prescription
free
and save
on refills
at
ADVAIRcopd.com.
[ Female Announcer ] SOME
PEOPLE LIKE TO PRETEND A FLOOD
COULD NEVER HAPPEN TO THEM.
AND THAT THEIR HOMEOWNERS
INSURANCE PROTECTS THEM.
[ THUNDER CRASHES ]
IT DOESN'T.
STOP PRETENDING.
ONLY FLOOD INSURANCE
COVERS FLOODS.
♪
VISIT FLOODSMART.GOV/PRETEND
TO LEARN YOUR RISK.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
YOU'RE WATCHING "STARTING
POINT."
LET'S BEGIN WITH JOHN BERMAN
WITH A LOOK AT TODAY'S TOP
STORIES.
>>> DANCING IN THE STREETS OF
PYONGYANG, TOASTING THE
COUNTRY'S FIRST SUCCESSFUL
SATELLITE LAUNCH INTO SPACE,
EVEN THOUGH THE U.S. GOVERNMENT
INDICATES THAT THE NORTH KOREANS
MIGHT NOT HAVE CONTROL OF THE
SATELLITE.
THE NORTH KOREAN GOVERNMENT
LOOKING AT THE LAUNCH.
AS LEADERS CALL FOR PUNISHMENT,
INSISTING THAT THE NORTH KOREANS
HAVE MOVED ONE STEP CLOSER TO
BEING ABLE TO LAUNCH NUCLEAR
WEAPONS ACROSS THE PACIFIC.
>>> AUTHORITIES IN BIRMINGHAM,
TAKING ANOTHER LOOK AT SECURITY
PROCEDURES AFTER A MAN SHOT AND
KILLED HIMSELF INSIDE THE
FEDERAL COURTHOUSE.
THE U.S. MARSHALS SAID THE MAN
WORKED IN THE BUILDING AND
SLIPPED THE GUN IN AS HE USED AS
EMPLOYEE ENTRANCE.
NO ONE IN THE COURTHOUSE WASSER
THREATENED.
>>> AN ASPIRING ACTOR AND COMIC
KILLED AFTER FULG INTO THE ROOF
OF THE INTERCONTINENTAL HOTEL IN
CHICAGO.
NICHOLAS WIEME WAS TAKING
PICTURES ON THE ONION ROOFTOP
ZONE WHEN HE FELL AND BECAME
WEDGED IN THE CHIMNEY.
IT TOOK HOURS FOR FIREFIGHTERS
TO GET TO HIM.
PRONOUNCED DEAD 45 MINUTES AFTER
THEY FREED HIM.
>>> SURVEILLANCE VIDEO CAPTURED
A CONFRONTATION BETWEEN A FEW
YOUNG MEN WHO POLICE SAY WERE
ARGUING OVER A BASKETBALL GAME.
ONE OF THE MEN, AS HE WAS
LEAVING, TURNED AND FIRED A
HANDGUN INTO THE TRAIN.
YOU SEE IT RIGHT THERE.
WOUNDING TWO PEOPLE.
PHILADELPHIA POLICE RIGHT NOW
SAY THEY ARE SEARCHING FOR
ASSAILANTS.
>>> THE UNIVERSITY OF IOWA, THE
FIRST PUBLIC UNIVERSITY IN THE
COUNTRY TO ASK ABOUT THEIR
GENDER IDENTITY AND SEXUAL
ORIENTATION ON APPLICATIONS.
STUDENTS AREN'T ASKED
SPECIFICALLY IF THEY ARE GAY,
ONLY IF THEY IDENTIFY WITH THE
LESBIAN, GAY, TRANSGENDER
COMMUNITY.
THIS IS AN OPTIONAL QUESTION
THAT WILL HELP THE UNIVERSITY
MEET STUDENT NEEDS AND TRACK
RETENTION RATES IN POPULATION.
SOLEDAD.
>> HMM.
NOT SURE HOW I FEEL ABOUT THAT.
I GUESS IN SOME WAYS GOOD TO BE
ABLE TO PROVIDE OPPORTUNITIES,
IF YOU HAVE A WHATEVER
PERCENTAGE OF GAY STUDENTS,
PEOPLE WHO ARE IDENTIFYING
HOWEVER THAT QUESTION IS
PHRASED.
BUT ON THE OTHER HAND, IT SEEMS
WEIRD TO ME.
CRICKETS.
OKAY.
>> I WOULD SAY THE UNIVERSITY OF
IOWA IS THE FIRST PUBLIC
INSTITUTION TO DO THIS, AND I'M
NOT SURE I WOULD HAVE WORDED THE
QUESTION EXACTLY THE WAY THEY
WORDED IT.
BUT I THINK IT'S A GOOD IDEA TO
KNOW WHAT --
>> HOW WOULD YOU WORD THE
QUESTION?
>> ARE YOU GAY OR LESBIAN?
THEY SEEMED TO HAVE MADE IT MORE
COMPLICATED THAN IT NEEDS TO BE.
>> WHY NOT JUST ASK THE QUESTION
YOU WANT THE ANSWER TO, RATHER
THAN ASKING AROUND THE QUESTION.
ULTIMATELY AND YOU DON'T HAVE TO
ANSWER.
YOU COULD JUST IGNORE THE
QUESTION.
>> IT COULD BE HELD AGAINST YOU.
>> YOU DON'T HAVE TO ANSWER, AND
ALSO THEY SAY IT'S THEIR
BUSINESS BECAUSE IT HELPS THEM
SERVE DIFFERENT POPULATIONS, THE
SAME WAY YOU ASK OPTIONALLY
ABOUT RACE.
>> YOU DON'T SAY DO YOU IDENTIFY
WITH WHITE PEOPLE?
>> THAT'S WHY I SAY IT'S A SILLY
WAY TO ASK THE QUESTION.
>> YOU START OFF VERY QUIETLY,
PEOPLE, BUT I APPRECIATE THE
CONVERSATION.
ZERO DARK THIRTY, HOTLY
ANTICIPATED THRILLER OVER THE
HUNT OF OSAMA BIN LADEN.
MAJOR BUZZ AND CONTROVERSY.
GRAPHIC DEPICTIONS OF BRUTAL
INTERROGATIONS, AND A YOUNG
OPERATIVE, PURPORTEDLY MODELED
ON A REAL CIA OPERATIVE.
WE HAVE LAUREN ASHBURN, DAILY
BEAST CONTRIBUTOR AND EDITOR IN
CHIEF OF THE DAILY DOWNLOAD.COM
TO TALK ABOUT THAT.
IT'S JUST A MOVIE.
WHY ARE PEOPLE GOING COMPLETELY
NUTS ABOUT THIS?
>> IT'S JUST A MOVIE.
THE WOMAN IN THE CENTER OF IT,
THE CIA OPERATIVE, WAS TRASHED
ON THE FRONT PAGE OF "THE
WASHINGTON POST" NASAID AS BEIN
ABRASIVE, A PASSED OVER FOR
PROMOTI
PROMOTION.
>> IT'S A DOCK YOU DRAMA IT'S A
MOVIE.
>> THIS REAL PERSON IS NOT ABLE
TO DEFEND HERSELF.
>> BUT THERE IS A BIG QUESTION
WHETHER OR NOT THE CIA ACTUALLY
GAVE THEM ALL OF THIS
INFORMATION, ALL OF THIS ACCESS.
THE WHITE HOUSE GAVE HER ACCESS.
WE DON'T KNOW WHO SHE IS.
>> SHE KNOWS WHO SHE IS.
>> FIRST OF ALL, SHE COULD HAVE
HER FRIENDS LEAK STUFF BACK THIS
IS HOW THE PRESS WORKS.
SHE COULD HAVE HER FRIENDS LEAK
STUFF BACK.
IT WOULD BE FINE, WORK IT OUT.
>> TORTURE, A HALF AN HOUR OF
TORTURE SCENES IN HERE.
>> AND I'M SURE THAT'S BECAUSE
THEY WANT TO TELL THE STORY IN
THE MOST ACCURATE HISTORICAL
CONTEXT, RIGHT?
>> I DON'T KNOW IF IT'S ACCURATE
OR HISTORICAL, IT'S A DOCUDRAMA.
>> IT'S FUN TO WATCH YOU FIGHT.
BUT SERIOUSLY, IS THERE A
REQUIREMENT -- YOU'VE DONE
MOVIES OBVIOUSLY.
IS THERE A REQUIREMENT THAT A
MOVIE ABOUT WAR HAS TO BE
ACCURATE.
THERE HAVE BEEN A TON OF MOVIES
AROUND A REAL TOPIC.
A REAL EXPERIENCE THAT HAVE
BEEN, YOU KNOW, TAKEN POETIC
LICENSE ON CERTAIN THINGS.
>> I HAVE NEVER MADE A FICTIONAL
MOVIE.
BUT IN A FICTIONAL MOVIE YOU CAN
DO WHATEVER YOU WANT AS LONG AS
YOU DON'T CALL IT A DOCUMENTARY.
THAT SAID, I THINK THE TORTURE
ISSUE GOES TO THE BROADER ISSUE
OF WHY WE'RE IN AFGHANISTAN, IN
A SENSE.
I'VE HAD THIS ARGUMENT WITH
PEOPLE.
AND VERY HAPPY WITH BIN LADEN
WAS KILLED.
AND THE POINT I MAKE, NO WAY WE
COULD HAVE KILLED BIN LADEN
WITHOUT BEING IN AFGHANISTAN,
AND YOU WON'T FLY S.E.A.L. TEAM
6 FROM VIRGINIA AND KILL HIM.
YOU DON'T GET THE INTEL AND
FORWARD OPERATING BASES.
WE HAD TO BE IN AFGHANISTAN TO
DO THAT.
THE MORAL QUESTION FOR AMERICA,
THAT WAS A CORRECT DECISION TO
BE AT WAR IN ORDER TO KILL THAT
PERSON?
THE FINER POINT, CAN YOU TORTURE
IN ORDER TO KILL SOMEONE YOU
NEED TO GET?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THE ANSWER IS.
>> THE FILMMAKER AND CATHLIN BIG
LOW ARE PRESENTING THIS AS A
JOURNALISTIC ENTERPRISE.
THEY ARE NOT CALLING IT A
DOCUDRAMA.
THEY GOT AN UNUSUAL DEGREE OF
ACCESS TO CIA, WHITE HOUSE,
WHICH WANTED TO SPIN THIS TO A
POSITIVE MOVIE OF OBAMA.
>> THE POSITIVE PIECE IN THE
CENTER, THE WOMAN GETTING THE
CREDIT FOR GETTING BIN LADEN
KILLED.
>> WHY IS THERE A WOMAN AT THE
CENTER OF THIS MOVIE?
>> IS IT MORE INTERESTING?
>> WASN'T THERE A WOMAN AT THE
CENTER OF THE STORY?
BASED ON A REAL CHARACTER,
RIGHT?
>> PART OF A TEAM.
AND I THINK SHE'S A HEROINE, AND
THAT'S WHY I COME BACK TO THE
NOTION SHE IS BEING TRASHED AND
SHE SHOULD BE GETTING A MEDAL.
>> I HAVEN'T SEEN "ZERO DARK
THIRTY."
CAN YOU SEPARATE TORTURE FROM
BIN LADEN?
HOW DOES THE MOVIE TREAT THAT
CONNECTION?
>> BASED ON CRITIC WHO'S HAVE
SEEN IT, THEY ARE SAYING THERE
IS A CLEAR IMPLICATION WE WOULD
HAVE NOT GOTTEN BIN LADEN IF --
>> TORTURE SEEMS TO HAVE WORKED,
SOFTENED UP THE CHARACTER, THE
PERSON WHO EVENTUALLY GAVE
INFORMATION.
>> INVESTIGATORS ARE NOT
CONVINCED WE WOULD HAVE GOTTEN
BIN LADEN.
>> YOU CAN'T SAY A MOVIE LIKE
ARGO, WHICH GOES OFTEN
DECLASSIFIED INFORMATION, DOES
NOT AT SOME POINT TAKE LICENSE
AND CREATE DRAMA IN CERTAIN
SCENES THAT DID NOT HAPPEN.
I DON'T BELIEVE THAT.
MISSISSIPPI BURNING CREATED
ENTIRE CHARACTERS AROUND A REAL
EVENT.
>> I THING ABOUT IT THE WOMAN
WHO GETS HIGHLIGHTED AT THE
CENTER, PEOPLE AT THE AGENCY WHO
HAD SOMETHING TO DO WITH IT ARE
NOW STARTING THIS WHOLE TRASH
TALK, SHE'S THIS, SHE'S THAT.
>> YOU CAN SAY IT'S JUST A
MOVIE, BUT MOVIES LIKE THIS, IT
LOOKS LIKE A BIG BOX OFFICE
MOVIE SHAPE PERCEPTION FOR A LOT
OF PEOPLE WHO DON'T FOLLOW
STORIES THAT CLOSELY.
>> THAT'S THEIR FAULT.
GO READ A NEWSPAPER.
DON'T RELY ON MOVIES AS YOUR
SOURCE OF NEWS.
>> DON'T YOU THINK ORGANIZATIONS
LIKE THE CIA HAVE DECIDED IT'S
IN THEIR BEST INTERESTS TO PUT
STORYLINES OUT THERE LIKE THIS.
>> I DON'T HAVE TO GUESS AT
THIS.
A WHOLE BUNCH OF E-MAIL TRAFFIC
THAT SHOWS CIA OPERATIVES SAYING
WE NEED TO PICK A WINNER.
THIS WILL BE BIG, WE NEED TO
COOPERATE.
>> IF YOU WERE IN THE WHITE
HOUSE, WOULDN'T YOU DO THIS?
COOPERATE AND SAY HERE IS THE
REAL SIDE OF THE STORY?
>> THE PROBLEM, WHAT ARE THE
MESSAGES?
WHAT MESSAGE IS IT TRYING TO
SEND?
THE MESSAGE TORTURE WORKS?
EVERYBODY COULD SEE, IF YOU
TORTURE SOMEBODY THEY WILL --
>> WHERE DOES IT LEAVE YOU?
WHERE DOES IT LEAVE YOU IF WE
ARE A COUNTRY THAT TORTURES
PEOPLE.
>> DO WHAT SEBASTIAN DOES, WRITE
NONFICTION, THE MESSAGE IS ONLY
TRUTH.
WHEN YOU VENTURE INTO FICTION
AND OPEN TO CRITICISM.
WHAT ARE YOU TRYING TO TELL US?
>> LIKE PO
>> HE SAYS HE WANTS IT TO BE
JUDGED AS A MOVIE, IT'S NOT A
DOCUMENTARY.
IT'S A MOVIE, NOT A DOCUMENTARY.
>>> WE HAVE TO TAKE A SHORT
BREAK.
STILL AHEAD, WE'LL TALK ABOUT
AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE, TAKEN
HERSELF OUT OF THE RUNNING FOR
SECRETARY OF STATE.
DOES THAT MEAN THAT SENATOR JOHN
KERRY IS A SHOO-IN?
A POSSIBLE CANDIDATE FROM ACROSS
THE AISLE.
TALK ABOUT THAT, NEXT.
JAYMI'S CHRISTMAS SHOPPING
AND WAS LOOKING FOR
GIFTS AT BEST BUY.
YOU WANNA SEE IF WALMART HAS
SIMILAR GIFTS FOR LESS?
YEAH.
LET'S GO.
SAMSUNG GALAXY S3 --
OVER FIFTY DOLLARS LESS
THAN BEST BUY!
WOW! FIFTY BUCKS!
YEAH!
THAT'S A PAIR OF SHOES.
SEE FOR YOURSELF IF YOU COULD
SAVE ON THE GIFTS YOU WANT.
WALMART.
[ Woman ]
♪ WHAT I WANT THIS SEASON
♪ IF YOU'D LIKE
TO TRY AND GUESS ♪
♪ IT IS SOMETHING VERY SPECIAL
♪ I WOULD READILY CONFESS
[ dogs barking ]
♪ 'CAUSE ALL I WANT
THIS SEASON ♪
♪ IS SOMETHING FROM YOUR HEART
♪ LA DA DA, LA DA DA
[ Male Announcer ] THINKING
OF OTHERS THIS HOLIDAY SEASON,
TRAVELERS.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
>>> SO THIS MORNING, WE HAVE
BEEN REPORTING THAT SUSAN RICE
HAS WITHDRAWN HER NAME FOR
CONSIDERATION AS SECRETARY OF
STATE.
REPEATED REPUBLICAN ATTACKS ON
HER CHARACTER ARE SHAMEFUL.
THE CONFIRMATION PROCESS WOULD
HAVE BEEN TOO DISRUPTIVE.
LISTEN.
>> I WITHDREW MY NAME, I THINK
IT'S THE RIGHT THING FOR THE
COUNTRY.
AND I THINK IT'S THE RIGHT THING
FOR THE PRESIDENT.
AND PUTTING THOSE THINGS
TOGETHER, THAT MAKES IT THE
RIGHT THING FOR ME AND MY
FAMILY.
>> WILL CANE, DO YOU THINK SHE
WAS PUSHED TO THIS BY
REPUBLICANS, OR MORE AT WORK
HERE?
>> I THINK THERE IS MORE AT WORK
HERE.
BUT CERTAINLY REPUBLICAN
OPPOSITION IN THE WAKE OF HER --
NOT TESTIMONY, BUT GOING OUT IN
FRONT OF AN AMERICAN AUDIENCE ON
SUNDAY SHOWS PLAYED A ROLE.
>> ABOUT BENGHAZI.
SUSAN RICE DIDN'T HAVE A STRONG
WELL OF DEMOCRATIC SUPPORT
BEHIND HER ANYWAY.
SHE HAD BEEN RULED TO NOT BE THE
MOST DIPLOMATIC PERSON IN WHAT
WOULD BE THE LEADING DIPLOMATIC
POST OF THE UNITED STATES.
>> SHE HAD ONE VERY IMPORTANT
SUPPORTER FOR THAT POST, THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES.
>> IS THIS THE PRESIDENT SHOWING
WEAKNESS?
AS SOME PEOPLE SUGGESTED?
THE PRESIDENT PUT INTO A CORNER
BY REPUBLICANS WHO STARTED
IMMEDIATELY SAYING THEY WOULDN'T
SUPPORT HER AS SECRETARY OF
STATE.
>> THE PRESIDENT IS TRYING TO
PICK THE FIGHTS HE CAN WIN.
HAVE YYOU HAVE TO LOOK AT WHAT
HAPPEN WITH THE FISCAL CLIFF
DEBATE.
THE PRESIDENT HAS TO CHOOSE
WHERE DOES HE HAVE TO GO ON THE
MAT?
THE FISCAL CLIFF, ISSUE OF
TAXES.
OR TWO FIGHTS, ONE ON SUSAN
RICE?
>> I THINK WHAT WOULD HAPPEN,
THE PRESIDENT DECIDED SHE WAS
PROBABLY NOT THE BEST PERSON TO
BE SECRETARY OF STATE FOR THE
COUNTRY, AND FOR OUR DIPLOMATIC
INITIATIVES.
SHE SERVED EXTREMELY WELL AT THE
U.N. AND SHE IS A TERRIFIC
DIPLOMAT.
BUT THERE -- JOHN KERRY SHOULD
BE SECRETARY OF STATE.
PERFECT FOR IT, AND COMING AFTER
HILLARY CLINTON, YOU NEED
SOMEONE WITH A BIG INTERNATIONAL
GRAVITAS.
AND JOHN KERRY WILL BE GREAT.
HE'S IN.
>> ALSO, A LOT OF PEOPLE HAVEN'T
HEARD ABOUT HER UNTIL NOW.
JOHN KERRY, EVERYONE KNOWS RICE,
LIKE FOR A LOT OF AMERICANS, WHO
IS THAT?
AND THE PRESIDENT WAS IN A
POSITION OF PUSHING SOMEONE
RELATIVELY UNKNOWN UNTIL THE
CONTROVERSY.
>> WE HAVE TO TAKE A SHORT
BREAK.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT TV.
ONE OF MY FAVORITE SUBJECTS.
CHANGED A LOT IN THE LAST
DECADE.
ONE OF THE MOST POPULAR CRITICS
SAY WE CAN THANK THE SOPRANOS
FOR THAT.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT THAT.
BACK IN JUST A MOMENT.
ything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Sharable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
Wooohooo....Hahaahahaha!
Oh...there you go.
I'm gonna stand
up to her!
No you're not.
I know.
You know Ronny folks who save
hundreds of dollars
switching to GEICO
sure are happy.
How happy are they Jimmy?
Happier than a witch in
a broom factory.
Get happy. Get GEICO.
Fifteen minutes could save you
fifteen percent or more.
Capella University understands
back from rough economic times.
Employees are being forced to do
more with less.
And the need for capable leaders
is greater than ever.
When you see these problems do
you take a step back,
or do you want to dive right in?
With a degree in business from
Capella University, you'll have
the knowledge to go further in
your career than you ever
thought possible.
Let's get started at CAPELLA.EDU
TIME FOR CITI PRICE REWIND.
BECAUSE YOUR DAUGHTER REALLY
WANTS THAT PINK CASTLE THING.
AND YOU REALLY DON'T WANT
TO PAY MORE THAN YOU HAVE TO.
ONLY CITI PRICE REWIND
AUTOMATICALLY SEARCHES
FOR THE LOWEST PRICE.
AND IF IT FINDS ONE, YOU GET
REFUNDED THE DIFFERENCE.
JUST USE YOUR CITI CARD
AND REGISTER YOUR PURCHASE
ONLINE.
HAVE A SUPER SPARKLY DAY!
OK.
[ Male Announcer ] NOW ALL
YOU NEED IS A MAGIC CARRIAGE.
CITI PRICE REWIND.
START SAVING
AT CITI.COM/PRICEREWIND.
(Announcer) When Subaru owners
look in the mirror,
they see more than themselves.
So we celebrate our year-end
with the "share the love" event.
Get a great deal on a new Subaru
and 250 dollars goes to your
choice of five charities.
By the end of this, our fifth
year,
our total can reach almost 25
million dollars.
It's a nice reflection on us
all.
Now through January 2nd.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO "STARTING
POINT."
FORMER PRESIDENT GEORGE H.W.
BUSH IS EXPECTED TO BE HOME
SOMETIME BEFORE CHRISTMAS.
HE'S BEEN IN A HOUSTON HOSPITAL
FOR THREE WEEKS RECOVERING FROM
A STUBBORN BOUT OF BRONCHITIS,
88 YEARS OLD THE OLDEST LIVING
FORMER PRESIDENT.
>>> THURSDAY NIGHT FOOTBALL, THE
STUMBLING BUMBLING PHILADELPHIA
EAGLES, THEY FUMBLED THE BALL
FOUR TIMES, THEY THREW AN
INTERCEPTION BUT THIS WAS THE
WORST.
THEY BLOCKED THEIR OWN PUNT.
YOU DON'T DO THAT IN FOOTBALL,
THAT HELPED THEM TO A 34-13 LOSS
AT HOME.
THEY DON'T TEACH YOU HOW TO DO
THAT.
>>> IF YOU NOTICED A CHANGE IN
YOUR TV VIEWING HABITS OVER THE
YEARS THERE ARE WHAT FEELS LIKE
DOZENS OF AWARD WINNING SHOWS ON
RIGHT NOW, "MADMEN" "BREAKING
BED," "DOWNTOWN ABBI" AND IT ALL
STARTED WITH "THE SOPRANOS."
THE BOOK IS CALLED "THE
REVOLUTION WAS TELEVISED."
NICE TO HAVE YOU WITH US.
>> THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
>> WHAT CHANGED TV DRAMA DO YOU
THINK?
>> WELL, WHAT HAPPENED WAS IN
THE MIDDLE TO LATE '90s, SO MANY
MORE CHANNELS WERE PRODUCING SO
MUCH PROGRAMMING THE AUDIENCE
FRACTURED.
ONE OF THE TIME THE GOAL WAS
WE'LL GET IT AS BIG AS POSSIBLE
AND DUMB IT DOWN, NOW THE
AUDIENCE IS SMALLER SO INSTEAD
OF TRYING TO AIM FOR WIDE NET
LET'S GO DEEP AND GET SOMETHING
THAT MAKES PEOPLE PASSIONATE
WHAT THEY DO.
HBO WAS WILLING TO GIVE CREATORS
TO WRITE IT.
>> DAVID CHASE DIDN'T SET OUT TO
WRITE A DRAMA, BUT WANTED TO
MAKE THE STAKES HIGH ENOUGH THAT
VIEWERS WOULD CARE.
THE WRITING HAS IMPROVED SO
MUCH.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT SOME OF THE
SHOWS WE JUST NAMED THERE HAVE
BEEN BUSINESS CHANGES, VIEWERS
STARTED REALLY TO EXPECT SOME
HIGH QUALITY WRITING IN DRAMAS.
>> BASICALLY THE TV DRAMAS ON
CABLE IN PARTICULAR OVER THE
LAST 15 YEARS REPLACED THE KINDS
OF MOVIES THAT ADULTS USED TO
EXPECT TO SEE.
NOW THE MOVIES ARE BLOCKBUSTERS
AND LOW BUDGET ART FILMS AND NOT
A WHOLE LOT IN BETWEEN.
NOW IF YOU WANT SERIOUS DRAMA
ABOUT ADULTS AND ADULT ISSUES
AND WHAT'S GOING ON IN AMERICA
YOU LOOK TO HBO AND FX AND AMC
AND SHOWTIME.
>> WHY IS THAT?
I WORKED AT A BROADCAST STATION
FOR A LONG TIME.
I USED TO WONDER WHY CAN'T WE
GET SOME OF THESE SHOWS?
>> THEY'VE TRIED AND THERE'S A
FEW BROADCAST SHOWS IN MY BOOK,
I WRITE ABOUT "LOST" AND THE
PROBLEM IS WITH BROADCAST THE
THRESHOLD IS HIGHER.
FOX DID A SHOW A COUPLE YEARS
AGO CALLED LONE STAR WHICH WAS
BASICALLY THEIR ATTEMPT TO DO AN
AMC STYLE SHOW, CANCELED AFTER
TWO EPISODES BECAUSE NOT ENOUGH
PEOPLE WATCHED.
>> PEOPLE EMBRACE AN ANTI-HERO
IN CABLE THAN ON NETWORK, PEOPLE
LIKE THE FLAWED, TERRIBLY
DAMAGED PERSON MANUFACTURING
DRUGS AND STUFF LIKE THAT, YOU
COULD SEE NETWORKS EXECUTIVES
BEING OH MY GOD, WE COULD NEVER
POSSIBLY HAVE THIS SHOW ON OUR
AIR.
>> ARCHIE BUNKER WAS AN
ANTI-HERO.
IT HAPPENED.
>> HE DID AN EPISODE WHEN HE
RUNS IN THE KU KLUX KLAN, THOSE
ARE THE RACIST.
ARCHIE IS JUST UGLY AND SAYS
OFFENSIVE THINGS.
>> I STILL MISS THE SOPRANOS.
WAS IT THE GREATEST TELEVISION
SERIES EITHER?
>> EITHER "THE SOPRANOS" OR "THE
WIRE."
>> WAS THE ENDING THE BEST
ENDING ON TELEVISION EVER?
>> IT IS CERTAINLY THE ENDING
WE'VE TALKED ABOUT THE MOST OF
ANY TELEVISION SHOW EVER AND I'M
STILL GETTING ARGUMENTS ABOUT IT
TO THIS DAY.
>> SIMON, HE TALKS ABOUT HOW I
REAL WRITER WANTS TO DO
SOMETHING, ENVISION A STORY THAT
HAS A BEGINNING, A MIDDLE AND AN
END AND SEEMS LIKE A DIFFERENT
FORMAT THAN YEAR AGO WHEN THE
GOAL WAS TO BE ON TV FOR AS LONG
YOU CAN, YOUR SHOW HAS AS MANY
SEASONS AS POSSIBLE.
VERSUS WE HAVE AN ARC AND WHEN
THAT STORY IS TOLD WE'RE DONE.
>> ONE OF THE THINGS THAT
HAPPENED A LOT DURING THIS
PERIOD, HAVE PRODUCERS GO TO THE
NETWORK HEADS AND SAY I WANT TO
END THIS SHOW, I'VE TOLD THE
STORY, THE PRODUCERS OF
"BATTLESTAR GALLATICA" AND IT'S
NO LONGER LET'S DRAG THIS OUT.
IT'S HERE'S THE STORY, TELL IT
IN THE BEST WAY POSSIBLE IN THE
MINIMUM AMOUNT OF TIME AND LET'S
GO BEFORE PEOPLE GET SICK OF US.
>> CHANGING VIEWING HABITS,
BECAUSE I WATCH "HOMELAND"
"BREAKING BAD," BUT SOMETHING
ELSE CHANGED, I WATCH THEM ALL
ON DEMAND OR I STREAM THEM.
I RARELY WATCH THEM WHEN THEY
AIR.
NOW, IT OCCURS TO ME THAT A LOT
OF THESE ARE FUNDED BY CHANNELS
BY PACKAGES WHERE YOU PAY FOR
100 CABLE CHANNELS AND I DON'T
WATCH 99 OF THEM.
IF WE MOVE TO ALA CARTE DO THESE
SERIES CONTINUE?
>> THAT'S WHAT I DON'T KNOW.
IF PEOPLE START CORD CUTTING,
THE NETWORKS HAVE MADE THINGS SO
EASY TO WATCH, IF PEOPLE SAY I
DON'T NEED MY CABLE, I JUST WANT
INTERNET THE MONEY MAY NOT BE
THERE FOR THE SHOWS.
NETFLIX IS STARTING TO PRODUCE
THEIR OWN SHOWS, ONE CALLED
"HOUSE OF CARDS" WITH KEVIN
SPACEY THAT'S THEIR ATTEMPT TO
BE THE NEXT HBO.
>> I SHOT SOMETHING FOR THAT.
I'M SO EXCITED, IN MARCH IT
COMES OUT.
>> YES.
>> THE BOOK IS CALLED "THE
REVOLUTION WAS TELEVISED."
ALAN SEPINWALL NICE TO HAVE YOU
WITH US.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>>> STILL AHEAD THE STORY OF
SOME BASKETBALL PLAYERS WHO LOST
THEIR HIGH SCHOOL BASKETBALL
GAME BY 105 POINTS.
IT WAS 107-2.
SO WAS THAT BAD SPORTSMANSHIP AT
WORK OR JUST GOOD OLD-FASHIONED
COMPETITION?
WE'LL TALK TO THE LOSING COACH
AND HER TEAM FROM BLOOMINGTON
SOUTH HIGH SCHOOL ABOUT THE BIG
LOSS, STRAIGHT AHEAD.
[ singing Christmas carols
in background ]
Aunt Sally's
singing again.
It's a tradition,
honey.
[ singing
Christmas carols ]
mmmm.
[ Female Announcer ]
Make new traditions
with Pillsbury Grands!
Cinnamon Rolls.
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
♪
BECOMING
PART OF THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
TREES WILL TALK TO NETWORKS
WILL TALK TO SCIENTISTS
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE.
CARS WILL TALK TO ROAD SENSORS
WILL TALK TO STOPLIGHTS
ABOUT TRAFFIC EFFICIENCY.
THE AMBULANCE WILL TALK
TO PATIENT RECORDS
WILL TALK TO DOCTORS
ABOUT SAVING LIVES.
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
THE NEXT BIG THING?
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
♪
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
♪
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
>>> DOWN TO THE WIRE, THE
PRESIDENT AND THE SPEAKER OF THE
HOUSE MEET FOR JUST UNDER AN
HOUR BUT STILL NO DEAL ON THE
FISCAL CLIFF AS CONGRESS GOES ON
VACATION TODAY.
ANY CHANCE WE'LL HAVE AN
AGREEMENT BEFORE THE YEAR ENDS?
>>> PLUS THE UNBELIEVABLE SCORE
OF A HIGH SCHOOL BASKETBALL
GAME, IT WAS 107-2.
WAS IT A LESSON IN BAD
SPORTSMANSHIP?
HEAR FROM THE LOSING COACH AND
THE PLAYERS STRAIGHT AHEAD.
>>> IS THERE A WAY TO GET THE
JOBLESS RATE DOWN TO 6.5%?
A LOOK AT THE FEDERAL RESERVE'S
GOAL AND WHAT IT WILL TAKE TO US
GET THERE.
>>> SENDING HELP BUT NOT ALL IN,
THE U.S. SENDING PATRIOT MISSILE
BATTERIES AND 400 U.S. TROOPS TO
TURKEY TO GUARD AGAINST SYRIA.
IS THIS A FIRST STEP IN A BIGGER
INVOLVEMENT.
>>> AND AIDAN BEGIN'S NEW MOVIE
"ALLEGIANCE."
IT'S FRIDAY, DECEMBER 14th AND
"STARTING POINT" BEGINS RIGHT
NOW.
SEBASTIAN JUNGER, AUTHOR OF NEW
eBOOK CALLED "A WORLD MADE OF
BLOOD" WE'LL TALK ABOUT THAT
BOOK IN A MOMENT, WILL CAIN,
COLUMNIST FOR THEBLAZE.COM AND A
WRITER FOR NEWWORKER.COM,
RICHARD SOCARIDES, EVERYONE
WEARING DARK THIS MORNING.
>> I HAD THE PASTEL, THE BRIGHT
PINK BUT SORRY.
>> STUCK CWITH NAVY.
>>> AMERICA INCHING CLOSER TO
THE FISCAL CLIFF, 18 DAYS WE GO
OVER, THAT MEANS TRIGGERING
MASSIVE TAX HIKES AND SPENDING
CUTS ALL AT THE SAME TIME.
THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES SET
TO GO HOME FOR THE HOLIDAYS
TODAY AND YESTERDAY THE
PRESIDENT AND SPEAKER BOEHNER
METAPHOR 50 MINUTES AND THEN
RELEASED A STATEMENT THAT DIDN'T
SAY A WHOLE HECK OF A LOT BUT
BOTH CALLED THE DISCUSSION FRANK
AND SAID THE LINES OF
COMMUNICATION REMAIN OPEN.
OUR SENIOR CONGRESSIONAL C
CORRESPONDENT DANA BASH IS HERE.
FORGET THE CHRISTMAS PLANS
YOU'RE PROBABLY NOT GOING TO BE
ENJOYING CHRISTMAS THIS YEAR?
>> NOBODY THINKS THEY'RE GOING
HOME FOR CHRISTMAS, IF THEY DO
MAYBE FOR A DAY AND COME BACK TO
WASHINGTON.
I'VE BEEN TALKING TO SOURCES IN
BOTH PARTIES THIS MORNING ABOUT
THAT MEETING YESTERDAY WITH THE
PRESIDENT, AND THE SPEAKER,
WHICH DID NOT GO VERY LONG, 50
MINUTES AND DID NOT GO ALL THAT
WELL.
WHAT WE NEED ARE NEW
PROPOSALS AND COMING TOGETHER
AND I'M TOLD BY BOTH PARTIES
THEY REALLY RESTATED THEIR
POSITIONS.
WHAT SEEMS TO BE GOING ON IS
FRANKLY I THINK BOTH SIDES ARE
TRYING TO RUN OUT THE CLOCK.
THE REPUBLICANS THEY KNOW THE
DEMOCRATS HAVE LEVERAGE AND THE
SPEAKER IS JUST WAITING
POTENTIALLY TO THE LAST MINUTE
SO HE CAN SAY I DID MY BEST, WE
HAVE TO RAISE MORE REVENUE AND
ON THE FLIPSIDE, THE DEMOCRATS
THE PRESIDENT KNOWS HE HAS
LEVERAGE AND HE'S RUNNING OUT
THE CLOCK.
IT'S WIN/WIN FOR HIM.
IF AT THE END OF THE DAY THE
REPUBLICANS CAVE ON TAX RATES,
GREAT.
IF NOT, AND GOD FORBID WE GO
OVER THE CLIFF HE KNOWS ALL THE
POLLING SHOWS REPUBLICANS WILL
TAKE THE BLAME.
>> WE MOVE AWAY TOWARD POLLING
AND A BIG FIX FOR THE BENEFIT OF
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE AS A WHOLE.
I KNOW YOU'VE HAD A CHANCE TO
TALK TO TWO FORMER SENATE
MAJORITY LEADERS EACH ON THE
OTHER SIDE OF THE AISLE.
>> SENATES LOTT AND DASCHLE,
THEY WORKED ON MANY ISSUES
TOGETHER AND THEY STILL THINK
THAT IT IS POSSIBLE TO GET A
DEAL, IT JUST HAS TO DO WITH THE
TIMING.
LISTEN TO WHAT THEY SAID.
>> I STILL AM CONVINCED AND
HOPEFUL AT LEAST THAT THEY'RE
GOING TO COME TO AN AGREEMENT.
THERE IS AN ARGUMENT THAT YOU
DON'T WANT TO MAKE IT TOO EARLY
BECAUSE THAT GIVES PEOPLE THAT
MAY NOT BE TOO HAPPY WITH IT
MORE TIME TO UNDERMINE IT SO THE
TEMPO AND THE TIMING IS
IMPORTANT.
>> I'VE HEARD PEOPLE SAY IN THE
LAST COUPLE OF DAYS, REPUBLICANS
AND DEMOCRATS SAID THE TIME HAS
COME FOR US TO PUT OUR COUNTRY
AHEAD OF OUR PARTY, AND THAT'S
REALLY WHAT IT'S GOING TO TAKE,
PUTTING THE COUNTRY AHEAD OF THE
PARTY.
>> EXACTLY WHAT YOU WERE JUST
SAYING, SOLEDAD, THE KEY
DIFFERENCE BETWEEN NOW AND THEN,
ABOUT A DECADE AGO, IS BOTH
PARTIES, MEMBERS OF CONGRESS OF
BOTH PARTIES ARE VERY CONCERNED
NOT JUST ABOUT GENERAL VOTERS
BUT ABOUT GETTING PRIMARY FROM
WITHIN THEIR OWN PARTY AND THAT
IS WHY IT IS SO MUCH MORE
DIFFICULT TO GET A DEAL.
>> DANA BASH THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
>>> LOTS OF PEOPLE HAVE BEEN
GIVING THE PRESIDENT SOME
ADVICE, DAN GLICKMAN WAS A
FORMER CONGRESSMAN, SERVED AS
SECRETARY OF AGRICULTURE UNDER
BILL CLINTON.
HE WRITES THIS IN "THE HUFGSTON
POST."
"I HAVE A HUMBLE SUGGESTION FOR
THE PRESIDENT TO GIVE THIS
DEBATE A NOBLE AND UNIFYING
CONGRESS.
THE PRESIDENT SHOULD SCHEDULE AN
ADDRESS SO HE CAN ARTICULATE TO
CONGRESS AND THE AMERICAN PEOPLE
WHO WHAT HE WITH DO BETTER THAN
MOST, ARE WE STILL A NATION
SACRIFICING A LITTLE FOR THE
GREATER GOOD?"
WHY DO YOU THINK A PRESENTATION
BEFORE A JOINT SESSION OF
CONGRESS VERSUS THE TWO OF THEM
SITTING IN A ROOM AND CONTINUING
TO TRY TO HASH OUT A DEAL IS A
BETTER WAY TO GO?
>> SOLEDAD THE ISSUES ARE VERY
BIG HERE.
THEY HAVE TO DO WITH THE FUTURE
OF THE COUNTRY, JOBS, ECONOMIC
SECURITY AND THESE ISSUES ARE
BEING DEBATED LIKE IT'S ANOTHER
POLITICAL CAMPAIGN, A QUESTION
OF POWER, WHO IS GOING TO WIN
AND WHO IS GOING TO LOSE AND I
DON'T THINK THE AMERICAN PEOPLE
REALLY UNDERSTAND WHAT'S GOING
ON THERE, OTHER THAN WASHINGTON
SEEMS TO BE AT IT'S GAMES AGAIN
LIKE IT PLAYED BEFORE THE
ELECTION.
ONLY THE PRESIDENT HAS THE BULLY
PULPIT.
WHILE I GENERALLY AGREE WITH THE
CONCEPTS HE'S PUT FORWARD,
SUBSTANTIVELY I THINK HE'S THE
ONLY PERSON WHO CAN TALK TO THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE, PAINT A PICTURE
AND CREATE A NARRATIVE WHY WE'RE
GOING THROUGH ALL THIS, TOTALLY
ABSENT FROM THIS DISCUSSION.
MOST AMERICANS THINK IT'S A
TRIBAL BATTLE IN WASHINGTON NOT
AFFECTING THEIR LIVES IN ANY
WAY.
>> PAINTING A PICTURE AND WHAT
YOU WROTE THE SPECIFICS ARE LESS
IMPORTANT THAN THE BIG PICTURE
RATIONALE AND ONE OF THE BIG
POINTS OF CONTENTION IS LACK OF
SPECIFICS.
WHAT ARE WE ACTUALLY THINKING
ABOUT CUTTING, EXACTLY WHAT WILL
THE TAX RATE BE, THINGS LIKE
THAT, I THINK PEOPLE WOULD ARGUE
THAT SPECIFICS, LACK OF SPERVEGS
HAS BEEN A BIG PROBLEM IN THIS
DEBATE.
>> THAT'S A QUESTION OF
LEADERSHIP AND BOTH THE
PRESIDENT AND THE CONGRESS HAVE
TO COME UP WITH THOSE SPECIFICS.
I'M REMINDED OF THE KENNEDY
ADDRESS, JOHN KENNEDY, ASK WHAT
YOU CAN DO FOR YOUR COUNTRY.
SOMEBODY HAS TO ASK THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE, THE WEALTHY AND OTHERS
AS WELL, THE WHOLE SOCIETY
WHETHER THEY'RE WILLING TO
SACRIFICE FOR THE GOOD OF THE
COUNTRY TO MAINTAIN AMERICA'S
STRENGTH IN ITS ECONOMY AROUND
THE WORLD.
NOBODY'S DONE THAT YET, AND
WE'VE SEEN PROPOSALS LIKE THE
SIMPSON-BOWLES PROPOSAL OR
DOMENICI PRF RI
DOMENICI-RIVLIN.
I THINK SOMEBODY HAS TO ASK THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE, HERE ARE THE
FACTS, HERE IS WHAT HAPPENS IF
WE DON'T DO ANYTHING, THAT'S NOT
GOOD FOR AMERICA AND REPUBLICANS
AND DEMOCRATS AND HAS TO BRING
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE INTO THE
DEBATE.
SO FAR THIS HAS BEEN AN INSIDE
WASHINGTON DEBATE.
>> HI, CONGRESSMAN, IT'S RICHARD
SOCARIDES.
I THINK IF WE ALL THINK ABOUT
THE SPEECH THAT BILL CLINTON
GAVE AT THE DEMOCRATIC
CONVENTI
CONVENTION, IF BARACK OBAMA
COULD GO BEFORE CONGRESS AND
GIVE THAT KIND OF A SPEECH NOW I
THINK IT WOULD REALLY HELP HIM
AND THE DEMOCRATS WIN THE DAY IN
THESE NEGOTIATIONS AND I THINK
THAT'S THE KIND OF THING YOU
WERE SUGGESTING, RIGHT?
>> IT IS BUT I THINK HE HAS TO
BE CAREFUL NOT TO GIVE A
PARTISAN SPEECH.
THIS IS A BIGGER SPEECH THAN
THIS.
THIS HAS TO DO WITH THE FUTURE
OF THE REPUBLIC.
AFTER ALL IF WE CAN'T EVEN ADD
OR SUBTRACT TOWER DEFICIT INTO
SOME REASONABLE WAY SO THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE HAVE SOME
PREDICTABILITY AND FISCAL SANITY
NOTHING IS GOING TO WORK.
HE'S THE ONLY ONE WHO CAN
ARTICULATE THIS TO THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE BUT IT HAS TO BE DONE IN
A WAY THAT'S NOT ENGAGED IN
POLITICAL GAMESMANSHIP.
>> I'M NOT A CYNIC.
SOMETIMES I AM BUT TODAY NOT
PARTICULARLY.
I DON'T SEE HOW A SPEECH SOMEHOW
BRINGS THE AMERICAN PEOPLE WHO
FEEL DISCONNECTED WITH A FISCAL
CLIFF DISCUSSION.
WHAT COULD I DO?
YOU DO A VERY MOVING, SAY AN
AMAZING SPEECH, MOVING, I LAUGH,
I CRY, I MOVE, TO DO WHAT?
>> THESE CONDITIONS ARE NOT A
MYSTERY.
THESE ARE THE SAME LINES FROM
THE SAME PEOPLE WE'VE BEEN
HEARING FOR 14 MONTHS.
I'M NOT QUITE SURE HOW SPEAKING
TO THEM IN FRONT OF A DIFFERENT
GROUP OF PEOPLE MAKES ANY
DIFFERENCE.
>> I'D LOVE TO THROW TO DAN, I'M
NOT SURE OF THE PRESIDENT'S
DESIRE TO DO WHAT YOU DESCRIBE.
WHICH IS TO MIX UP THE FISCAL
CLIFF AND OUR LONG-TERM DEBT
SITUATION.
I'VE SEEN NO DESIRE COMING FROM
THE WHITE HOUSE TO DEAL WITH
BOTH ISSUES AT THE SAME TIME.
>> FIRST OF ALL I RECOGNIZE IT'S
MAYBE RATHER LATE TO DO A SPEECH
TODAY.
THE PRESIDENT JUST CAN'T DO A
SPEECH WITHOUT GETTING THE
SPEAKER'S PERMISSION TO DO THAT
KIND OF THING BUT IF YOU LOOK AT
THE ISSUE BIGGER THAN JUST WHAT
THE TAX RATES ARE GOING TO BE OR
WHAT THE ENTITLEMENT CUTS ARE
GOING TO BE, THIS HAS TO DO WITH
THE FISCAL STABILITY AND
STRENGTH OF AMERICA, TO BE THE
LEADER IN THE WORLD.
THESE ARE FUNDAMENTAL ISSUES,
SOMEBODY HAS TO ARTICULATE THE
SIGNIFICANCE WHAT HAVE WE'RE
TALKING ABOUT TO THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE SO THEY UNDERSTAND IT,
AND IT HAS TO BE DONE IN A
NONPOLITICAL, NONPARTISAN WAY.
>> DAN GLICKMAN JOINING US,
FORMER DEMOCRATIC CONGRESSMAN
AND FORMER AGRICULTURE SECRETARY
UNDER PRESIDENT CLINTON, NICE TO
HAVE YOU WITH US SIR.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>>> JOHN BERMAN HAS AN UPDATE ON
STORIES.
>> BIG NEWS ABOUT SYRIA'S
ONGOING CIVIL WAR AND A NEW ROLE
FOR THE UNITED STATES.
DEFENSE SECRETARY LEANNE PANETTA
SIGNED AN ORDER FOR TWO PATRIOT
MISSILE BATTERIES AND 400
AMERICAN TROOPS.
THIS MOVE WAS EXPECTED AS THE
REBELLION IN SYRIA DESTABILIZES
THE ASSAD REGIME.
NICK PATTON WALON WALSH, WHAT I
PICK SNUR.
>> THE GERMANS ARE EXPECTED TO
CONTRIBUTE PATRIOT MISSILES.
WE'RE LOOKING AT SEEING A
VARIETY OF NATO NATIONS
CONTRIBUTE TROOPS TO THE AREA,
THE U.S. NOT SURE WHERE THEY'LL
STATION THERE.
THIS BRINGS U.S. TROOPS INTO THE
VOLUME TIRE AREA.
LET ME GIVE YOU THE BACK STORY,
ABOUT TWO OR THREE MONTHS AGO
THERE WERE EXCHANGES OF FIRE
WHEN THE SYRIAN ARMY WAS ACCUSED
OF SHOOTING INTO TURKEY, TROUBLE
CONCERNED THEY MAY TRY TO DRAW
TURKEY INTO THE WAR.
LEON PA NET TA SAYING THERE IS A
PLAN IN PLACE IN CASE THE ASSAD
REGIME USES CHEMICAL WEAPONS.
NATO SAYS THEY'RE THERE PURELY
TO DEFEND TURKEY.
>> NICK PATON WALSH THIS
MORNING.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL MEET
WITH SUSAN RICE THIS MORNING,
WITHDRAWI INING HER NAME TO REP
HILLARY CLINTON AS SECRETARY OF
STATE.
>> I DIDN'T WANT TO SEE A
CONTIRMCO
CONFIRMATION PROCESS THAT WAS
PROLONGED, POLITICIZED, VERY
DISTRACTING AND VERY DISRIPPIVE
BECAUSE THERE ARE SO MANY THINGS
WE NEED TO GET DONE AS A
COUNTRY.
>> RICE WAS REPEATEDLY
CRITICIZED BY SENATE REPUBLICANS
FOR STATEMENTS SHE MADE ABOUT
THE CAUSE OF THE DEADLY ATTACK
ON THE U.S. CONSULATE IN
BENGHAZI IN SEPTEMBER.
SHE ORIGINALLY SAID THE VIOLENCE
STARTED OVER ANGER ABOUT THAT
ANTI-MUSLIM FILM.
LIVE LOOK AT A RALLY IN CAIRO IN
EGYPT THIS IN SUPPORT OF
PRESIDENT MOHAMED MORSI AHEAD OF
TOMORROW'S REFERENDUM ON THE NEW
CONSTITUTIONAL PROPOSAL.
MEMBERS OF THE OPPOSITION SAY
THE DISCUSSION IS TOO ISLAMIST
AND INFRINGES ON MINORITY
RIGHTS, THEY'RE APPARENTLY
PROTESTING OUTSIDE THE
PRESIDENTIAL PALACE RIGHT NOW.
>>> SECURITY GUARDS AT NEW
YORK'S JFK AIRPORT COULD WALK
OFF THE JOB NEXT WEEK JUST IN
TIME FOR THE HOLIDAY TRAVEL
RUSH.
THERE ARE 300 GUARDS THAT HANDLE
TRAFFIC IN FRONT OF THE
TERMINALS AND HELP SECURE TARMAC
GATES SO HAPPY HOLIDAYS,
TRAVELERS.
>>> LOOK AT THIS PICTURE OF A
HIGH SCHOOL BASKETBALL
SCOREBOARD, YES, 107-2, THAT IS
NOT A MISTAKE.
THERE ARE SOME CALLS FOR THE
WINNING COACH, THE WINNING COACH
TO BE FIRED FOR ALLOWING SUCH A
CRUSHING LOSS.
WE'LL HEAR FROM THE LOSING
TEAM'S COACH AND THEIR PLAYERS,
THAT'S COMING UP NEXT.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
SO WE WANT TO START THIS MORNING
SHOWING YOU A SCOREBOARD.
YOU'RE NOT MISREADING THE SCORE
OF THE BASKETBALL GAME, 107-2,
THE FINAL SCORE OF A GIRL'S HIGH
SCHOOL BASKETBALL GAME, THE
BLOOMINGTON SOUTH LADY PANTHERS
WON, THEY DEFEATED THE ARLINGTON
HIGH SCHOOL GOLDEN KNIGHTS, THE
KNIGHTS ARE MADE UP OF A NUMBER
OF YOUNG WOMEN WHO NEVER PLAYED
ON A VARSITY TEAM.
THE SIGN WAS REALLY AN
INDICATION OF BAD SPORTSMANSHIP.
TEAM MEMBERS JOIN US ALONG WITH
THEIR COACH.
NICE TO HAVE YOU GUYS WITH US.
WE APPRECIATE IT.
I'M GOING TO START WITH YOU,
COACH, IF I CAN.
TELL ME HOW EVERYBODY IS FEELING
AFTER WHAT NOT ONLY WAS IT A
DEVASTATING LOSS, EVERYBODY WAS
TALKING ABOUT IT, IT MADE
HEADLINES ALL OVER THE PLACE.
HOW ARE YOU GUYS FEELING ABOUT
THAT?
>> WELL, WE WERE, WE WEREN'T
SHOCKED THE NEXT MORNING BUT
THEN AGAIN WE WERE IN SHOCK.
IT'S A HUMBLING EXPERIENCE AND
AT THE END OF THE DAY WE'RE
BLESSED BECAUSE WE HAVE ONE
ANOTHER AND WE JUST GO BACK TO
THE GRIND ON THE BASKETBALL
COURT THE NEXT MORNING, SO IT
WAS SHOCKING NEWS BUT WE GOT
OVER IT AND WE JUST ARE BACK ON
THE GROUND ON THE BASKETBALL
COURT.
>> BRIOLETTE YOU'RE A FRESHMAN
AT ARLINGTON.
HAVE YOU PLAYED BASKETBALL
BEFORE?
WHAT WENT WRONG THAT THE SCORE
WAS SO LOPSIDED?
>> YES, I'VE PLAYED BASKETBALL
BEFORE AND I THINK WHAT WENT
WRONG WAS THAT WE JUST, IT WAS A
STRUGGLE BECAUSE NOT EVERYBODY
ON THE TEAM HAS PLAYED BEFORE
AND THIS WAS A VARSITY GAME, AND
IT WAS MORE COMPETITIVE BECAUSE
THEY'VE PLAYED LONGER THAN MOST
OF US AND THEY JUST WORK, THEY
WORK VERY HARD AND WE JUST
HAVEN'T PLAYED BEFORE AND IT WAS
PROBABLY REALLY HARD FOR ALL OF
US AS A TEAM.
>> COACH, LET ME ASK YOU A
QUESTION SOME OF THE FALLOUT
PEOPLE WERE SAYING THERE SHOULD
HAVE BEEN A MERCY RULE MEANING
THEY SHOULD HAVE FIGURED OUT HOW
TO AFTER A CERTAIN NUMBER OF
POINTS WERE SCORED PLAYED THE
GAME DIFFERENTLY, MAYBE THE
OPPOSING TEAM STOP SHOOTING ON
YOU, MAYBE STOP THE GAME,
WHATEVER.
SORT OF VARIOUS VERSIONS OF WHAT
SHOULD HAVE HAPPENED.
LETTING THE GAME GO ON SO LONG
THAT WAS REALLY BAD
SPORTSMANSHIP.
DO YOU SEE IT THAT WAY FROM THE
OPPOSING TEAM?
>> NO, I DON'T SEE IT THAT WAY.
I WAS ASKED ABOUT THE MERCY RULE
AND I DO NOT BELIEVE IN THE
MERCY RULE.
I JUST BELIEVE IN CHARACTER AND
THIS IS THE GAME OF BASKETBALL,
AND I BELIEVE THAT ALL RULES AND
REGULATIONS SHOULD STAY THE
SAME, BUT I BELIEVE THAT THIS IS
A TIME FOR THE OPPOSING TEAM OR
OURSELVES, WHICHEVER WAY THE
GAME IS GOING IF IT'S A LOPSIDED
SCORE THAT THE TEAM WORKS ON
SOMETHING THEY'VE NEVER WORKED
ON BEFORE AND THEREFORE THAT
WILL MILK TIME OFF THE CLOCK
EVENTUALLY AND YOU WON'T HAVE TO
GO THROUGH THE NURTURING PHASE
AS I HAVE BEEN WITH MY GIRLS BUT
NONETHELESS IT'S BEEN A
BLESSING.
>> SO I HAVE A QUESTION.
WHO SCORED THE TWO POINTS THAT
YOU GOT?
>> RIGHT HERE, FREE-THROWS.
>> THAT'S YOUR HERO.
>> AND YOU BUILT FROM THERE.
>> THAT WAS IT.
YOU GUYS HAVE LOST 23 GAMES.
YOU'VE REALLY HAD A TOUGH TIME
AND THE SCHOOL WAS TAKEN OVER
BECAUSE OF SOME ACADEMIC ISSUES
SO THERE'S A LEVEL, EVERYBODY
HAS TO HAVE A C GRADE POINT
AVERAGE ON THE TEAM OR THEY'RE
NOT ALLOWED TO PLAY.
IT'S BEEN A CHALLENGE FOR YOU.
MIKE EPPS THE ACTOR CAME IN,
GAVE A TALK TO THE TEAM AND SAID
LISTEN THERE'S A LOT OF GROWTH
THAT CAN BE HAD BASICALLY IN
LOSING, WHEN YOU LOSE, YOU CAN
COME BACK FROM THAT IN A BIG
WAY.
WHAT'S THE STRATEGY COACH NOW
AND HOW ARE YOU BRINGING YOUR
GIRLS ALONG, YOUR YOUNG LADIES
ALONG FOR THE NEXT GAMES?
>> WELL, EVER SINCE THE GAME HAD
ENDED AND ALL THIS HAS COME
ABOUT, OUR MINDS HAVE NOT
CHANGED.
THEY ARE THE SAME AS IF THIS WAS
THE FIRST GAME OF THE SEASON,
JUST STAYING HUMBLE, WORKING
HARD, CONTINUOUS EFFORT EVERY
SINGLE DAY AND KEEPING A SMILE
ON OUR FACE AND BASICALLY STILL
GETTING AFTER IT IN THE
CLASSROOM FIRST AND WE JUST
HAVEN'T CHANGED WHO WE ARE AND
HOW WE DO THINGS, AND I JUST
TELL MY GIRLS EVERY SINGLE DAY,
IT'S ABOUT GETTING BETTER,
GROWING RELATIONSHIPS AND
BUILDING OUR CHARACTER AT THE
END OF THE DAY, SO WE HAVEN'T
CHANGED ANYTHING.
>> I THINK THAT'S TRUE.
I COMPLETELY SUPPORT THAT, AND
YES, IN THE CLASSROOM FIRST AND
FOREMOST, AND THEN ON THE
BASKETBALL COURT AFTER THAT.
COACH EBONY JACKSON JOINING US,
BRIELLA THOMPSON AND HER
TEAMMATES JOINING US FROM THE
ARLINGTON HIGH SCHOOL GOLDEN
KNIGHTS WOMEN'S BASKETBALL TEAM.
THEY HAVE A GREAT SCHOOL, I HAD
A CHANCE TO TOUR IT, A GREAT
RESTART AND FOCUSING ON
ACADEMICS.
>> ONE OF LIFE'S GREATEST
LESSONS YOU'RE NOT GOING TO
AVOID FAILURE AND ADVERSITY,
IT'S WHAT HAPPENS AFTER THAT.
HERE YOU GO, HERE IS YOUR
OPPORTUNITY.
>> LOVE THAT.
YOU PUT THAT SO WELL, WILL CAIN.
WE HAVE TO TAKE A SHORT BREAK.
>>> IS THERE A WAY TO GET THE
UNEMPLOYMENT RATE TO 5%?
LOOK AT WHAT THE FEDERAL RESERVE
IS TRYING TO DO TO GET THERE.
E
ROI THROUGH SEO
ALL BY COB.
AND YOU...RENT FROM NATIONAL.
BECAUSE ONLY NATIONAL LETS YOU
CHOOSE ANY CAR IN THE AISLE...
AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE
A FULL-SIZE OR ABOVE,
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
I'M GOING B-I-G.
[ Male Announcer ] GOOD CHOICE
BUSINESS PRO. GOOD CHOICE.
GO NATIONAL.
GO LIKE A PRO.
I NEED YOU.
I FEEL SO ALONE.
BUT YOU'RE NOT
ALONE.
I KNEW YOU'D COME.
LIKE I COULD STAY AWAY.
YOU KNOW I CAN'T DO THIS
WITHOUT YOU.
YOU'LL NEVER HAVE TO.
YOU'RE ALWAYS THERE
FOR ME.
SHH!
I'LL GET YOU
A RENTAL CAR.
I COULD ALSO USE
AN UMBRELLA.
FALL IN LOVE WITH
PROGRESSIVE'S CLAIMS SERVICE.
>>> GOOD MORNING, I'M CLPS CLS
WATCHING YOUR MONEY.
U.S. STOCK FUTURES ARE UP
SLIGHTLY BUT WORRIES ABOUT THE
FISCAL CLIFF PERSIST.
THE S&P 500 SNAPPED A "360" DAY
WINNING STREAK DESPITE MODEST
ECONOMIC DATA.
THE S&P IS STILL UP ALMOST 13%
THIS YEAR.
STARTING TO BE SOME WORRIES
GOING OVER THE FISCAL CLIFF
WE'LL SEE A RETURN OF SOME OF
THE GAINS.
>>> BEN BERNANKE SAYS THE FED
STIMULUS WILL CONTINUE UNTIL THE
JOBLESS RATE FALLS TO 6.5%, A
FULL PERCENTAGE POINT FROM WHERE
WE ARE RIGHT NOW.
TO GET THERE IN ONE YEAR ONE
ECONOMIST TOLD CNN MONEY WE NEED
TO CREATE 270,000 JOBS A MONTH.
TO GET THERE IN TWO YEARS WE
NEED 200,000 JOBS PER MONTH.
THE GROWTH RIGHT NOW ABOUT
150,000 A MONTH SO GROWTH AT
THAT RATE IS UNLIKELY.
IT COULD MEAN AT THIS RATE IT
COULD TAKE UNTIL 2018 TO REACH
6.5% UNEMPLOYMENT.
IF HIRING STAYS LIKE IT RIGHT
NOW THE JOB WON'T TURN INTO A
PRE-RECESSION 5% UNTIL 2025.
>> BERNANKE IS SAYING THEY'LL
KEEP THE RATE AT THAT LEVEL
UNTIL THEN.
>> THEY'LL KEEP INTEREST RATES
LOW AND KEEP STIMULATING UNTIL
WE GET BACK TO 6.5%, SO THAT
MEANS THE FED WILL KEEP PROPPING
THINGS UP AS LONG AS THEY CAN.
>>> STILL AHEAD ON "STARTING
POINT" REMINDING PEOPLE OF THE
TRAYVON MARTIN CASE, THE
17-YEAR-OLD SHOT TO DEATH IN
FLORIDA, A MAN SAID THAT
APPARENTLY THE MUSIC IN THE CAR,
THE BOYS WERE RIDING, WAS TOO
LOUD AND THERE'S A CHANCE THE
FACT THAT THE SHOOTER COULD USE
THE CONTROVERSIAL STAND YOUR
GROUND LAW AS HIS DEFENSE.
WE'LL TALK TO THE PARENTS OF THE
YOUNG MAN WHO WAS SHOT AND
KILLED, JORDAN DAVIS' PARENTS
WILL JOIN TO US TALK ABOUT THAT
CASE COMING UP.
>>> AND A WOUNDED WARRIOR, WAS
HE MISTREATED ON A RECENT DELTA
FLIGHT?
WHAT WITNESSES SAY HAPPENED TO
HIM, A U.S. VETERAN, THAT HAS
THEM OUTRAGED, AHEAD AS WELL.
Again?
It's embarrassing
It's embarrassing!
We can see you Carl.
We can totally see you.
Come on you're better than
this...all that prowling around.
Yeah, you're the
king of the jungle.
Have you thought about going
vegan Carl?
HAHAHA!!
You know folks who save hundreds
of dollars by
switching to GEICO
sure are happy.
How happy are they Jimmy?
Happier than antelope with
night-vision goggles.
Nice!
Get happy. Get GEICO.
Fifteen minutes could save you
fifteen percent or more.
TO THE BEST VACATION
SP(ALL) THE GULF!
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHICH OF
OUR GREAT STATES FOLKS VISIT.
MISSISSIPPI,
ALABAMA,
LOUISIANA
OR FLORIDA,
THEY'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
SHAUL, YOUR ALABAMA
HOSPITALITY IS INCREDIBLE.
THANKS, KAREN.
LOVE YOUR MISSISSIPPI OUTDOORS.
I VOTE FOR YOUR
FLORIDA BEACHES, DAWN.
BILL, THIS LOUISIANA
SEAFOOD IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR ON THE GULF,
WE'VE DECIDED TO PUT
ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
NOW IS THE PERFECT TIME TO
VISIT ANYONE OF OUR STATES.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE, GO FISHING
OR JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
WE'VE GOT COASTLINE TO EXPLORE
AND WILDLIFE TO PHOTOGRAPH.
AND THERE'S WORLD CLASS DINING
WITH OUR WORLD FAMOUS SEAFOOD.
SO FOR A GREAT VACATION
THIS YEAR, COME TO THE GULF.
ITS ALL FABULOUS BUT
I GIVE FLORIDA THE EDGE.
RIGHT AFTER MISSISSIPPI.
YOU MEAN ALABAMA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
THIS INVITATION IS
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP
AND ALL OF US WHO
CALL THE GULF HOME.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
WITH SCOTTRADER
STREAMING QUOTES,
ANY WAY YOU WANT.
FULLY CUSTOMIZE IT
FOR YOUR TRADING PROCESS --
FROM THOUGHT TO TRADE,
ON EVERY SCREEN.
AND ALL IN REAL TIME.
WHICH MAKES IT JUST LIKE
HAVING YOUR OWN TRADING FLOOR,
RIGHT AT YOUR FINGERTIPS.
[ Rodger ] AT SCOTTRADE,
SEVEN DOLLAR TRADES
ARE JUST THE START.
TRY OUR
EASY-TO-USE
SCOTTRADER
STREAMING QUOTES.
IT'S ANOTHER REASON
MORE INVESTORS ARE SAYING...
[ All ]
I'M WITH SCOTTRADE.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
YOU'RE WATCHING "STARTING
POINT."
JOHN BERMAN HAS A LOOK AT THE
DAY'S TOP STORIES FOR US.
>> A TEEN IS CHARGED WITH
ATTACKING A MEDAL OF HONOR
RECIPIENT.
KENTUCKY STATE POLICE SAY DAKOTA
MAYER GOT IN A FIGHT WITH A
PARTY.
IT'S NOT CLEAR WHAT THE FIGHT
WAS ABOUT.
HE WAS GIVEN THE NATION'S
HIGHEST MILITARY HONOR AFTER HE
RISKED HIS LIFE TO SAVE THREE
DOZEN TROOPS CAUGHT IN A
FIREFIGHT.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA IS TALKING
ABOUT LEGALIZED POT SINCE THE
FIRST TIME COLORADO AND
WASHINGTON STATE APPROVED IT.
THE PRESIDENT TELLS ABC'S
BARBARA WALTERS HE DOES NOT
SUPPORT WIDESPREAD LEGALIZATION
AT THIS POINT.
THE BIG NEWS AS FOR GOING AFTER
USERS IN THE STATES THAT HAVE
LEGALIZED MARIJUANA HE SAYS "IT
WOULD NOT MAKE SENSE FOR US TO
SEE A TOP PRIORITY AS GOING
AFTER RECREATIONAL USERS IN
STATES THAT HAVE DETERMINED IT'S
LEGAL."
IT DOESN'T SOUND LIKE HE'LL BE
GOING AFTER PEOPLE SMOKING POT.
WHEN ASKED ABOUT HIS OWN POT USE
HE MENTIONED IN HIS MEMOIR
"DREAMS OF MY FATHER" HE SAID
THERE ARE MANY THINGS HE REGRETS
DOING, THAT SUBSTANCE ABUSE
ISN'T GOOD FOR KIDS AND THAT
IT'S SOMETHING OF COURSE HE
WANTS TO DISCOURAGE.
>>> SOME VETERANS ARE ANGRY WITH
DELTA AIRLINES FOR WHAT THEY
FEEL IS DISRESPECTFUL TREATMENT
GIVEN TO A FELLOW VETERAN.
MARINE LANCE CORPORAL CHRISTIAN
BROWN LOST BOTH LEGS AND "THE
WASHINGTON POST" SAYS VETERAN ON
THE FLIGHT FROM DELTA, HE WAS
CLUMSILY WHEELED TO THE BACK OF
THE PAIN, HE WAS PAINED AND
HUMILIATED AND WHEN THE CREW WAS
ASKED TO MOVE BROWN TO FIRST
CLASS THEY REFUSED.
DELTA SAYS THE INCIDENT IS UNDER
INVESTIGATION AND THAT SERVICE
MEMBERS ARE ALWAYS HELD IN HIGH
REGARD.
>>> TALK ABOUT PUTTING PEOPLE ON
THE SPOT, A COUPLE OF STUDENTS
AT BYU HAD A LITTLE FUN WITH
STUDENTS STAGING A FAKE
CHRISTMAS SURVEY UNDERNEATH SOME
SURPRISE MISTLETOE THAT CAME
DOWN FROM THE SKY.
THEY GOT A FEW PECKS OUT OF IT
AND ONE OPEN PALMED SLAP.
TAKE A LOOK.
>> MISTLETOE LIKE OVER THE DOOR.
>> I GUESS SO.
>> OR WOULD YOU?
>> WOULD I?
>> YES.
>> I HAVE NEVER TO DONE IT.
>> BUT YOU WOULD DO IT.
>> I WOULD DO IT.
>> OKAY.
>> OH!
>> WHOA, HEY.
>> MERRY CHRISTMAS, THANK YOU.
>> ALL RIGHT, I'LL GO FOR IT.
>> OKAY.
>> GREAT.
BEST I'VE EVER TAKEN.
>> IT SEEMS LIKE IT'S GOING SO
WELL BUT THEN AUTOGRAPH, I TELL
YOU.
EVERYONE CAN'T BE A WINNER ON
THAT.
THAT'S CUTE, VERY CUTE.
>>> WE TURN TO A STORY WE'VE
BEEN FOLLOWING NOW FOR SEVERAL
WEEKS AND IT IS A TOUGH, TOUGH
STORY, THE MAN WHO KILLED
17-YEAR-OLD JORDAN DAVIS IN A
FLORIDA PARKING LOT IS SCHEDULED
TO APPEAR IN COURT ON MONDAY.
HE IS 45 YEARS OLD, HIS NAME IS
MICHAEL DUNN AND HE IS CHARGED
WITH FIRST-DEGREE MURDER AND
THREE COUNTS OF ATTEMPTED MURDER
FOR FIRING INTO A CAR WHERE
DAVIS AND THREE OF HIS FRIENDS
WERE SITTING.
DUNN SAYS HE FELT THREATENED BY
THE TEENAGERS, AFTER HE ASKED
THEM TO TURN DOWN THEIR MUSIC,
SO IT WAS BASICALLY OVER LOUD
MUSIC AND THAT HE SHOT THEM IN
SELF-DEFENSE, AND THERE IS SOME
WORD HIS FIRST ATTORNEY SAID
THAT THEY MIGHT FOCUS ON
FLORIDA'S CONTROVERSIAL STAND
YOUR GROUND LAW IN HIS DEFENSE.
NOW SINCE THEN HE HAS SWITCHED
ATTORNEYS.
JOINING TO US TALK ABOUT THIS IS
LUCIA McBETH AND RON DAVIS,
JORDAN DAVIS' PARENTS AND THEIR
ATTORNEY AS WELL JOHN PHILLIPS.
IT HAS BEEN A HORRIFIC THREE
WEEKS FOR YOU.
I CANNOT IMAGINE HOW AWFUL IT
HAS BEEN, IF YOU CAN, MS.
McBETH, TELL ME HOW YOU FOUND
OUT THAT JORDAN HAD BEEN KILLED.
WHAT HAPPENED?
>> A PHONE CALL FROM HIS FATHER,
MY HUSBAND AND I WERE IN CHICAGO
FOR THANKSGIVING AND I HAPPENED
TO COME UP TO THE BEDROOM AND I
SAW RON'S NAME POP UP, AND I
KNEW THE MOMENT I SAW HIS NAME,
THAT LATE AT NIGHT, I KNEW IT
HAD TO DO WITH JORDAN.
>> DID YOU KNOW IT HAD TO BE
BAD?
>> I KNEW IN MY SPIRIT IT WAS
NOT GOOD.
I KNEW THAT IT COULD NOT BE GOOD
THAT LATE AT NIGHT FOR HIM TO BE
CALLING.
>> WHEN DID YOU, MR. DAVIS,
LEARN THE DETAILS OF WHAT HAD
HAPPENED IN THE PARKING LOT?
BECAUSE THE SHOOTING WAS
HORRIFIC, BUT THE DETAILS AROUND
THE SHOOTING AWFUL AS WELL.
>> YES.
ITS FIRST CALL I GOT WAS FROM
THE BEST FRIEND OF MY SON, AND
HE HAD PHONED HIS MOTHER WHILE
IN THE CAR AND HIS MOTHER CALLED
ME AND I RUSHED TO THE HOSPITAL
TO SEE ABOUT MY SON AND WHEN I
FOUND OUT THAT HE HAD BEEN SHOT
AND KILLED AND THE WAY THAT WE
BEEN SHOT AND KILLED, I GOT HOME
AND TOLD MY WIFE WHAT HAPPENED,
AND IT WAS THE MOST EXCRUCIATING
THING.
I MEAN, IT JUST TEARS AT YOUR
GUT AND TEARS AT YOUR HEART ALL
AT THE SAME TIME AND YOU'RE
UNSTEADY AND THEN TO MAKE THAT
CALL TO HER, AND JUST TO, JUST
TO TRY TO SOFTEN THE BLOW, YOU
KNOW, JUST A LITTLE BIT FOR HER,
BECAUSE THAT'S OUR ONLY CHILD,
THE ONLY CHILD WE WERE GOING TO
HAVE TOGETHER AND HE WAS A
SPECIAL CHILD.
HE WAS JUST GREAT, A GREAT,
GREAT CHILD, AND WE'LL NEVER
RECOVER FROM IT, AND THIS
GENTLEMAN HAS JUST TORN THE
FABRIC OF OUR FAMILY APART.
>> BEFORE WE TALK ABOUT YOUR
SON, LET'S TALK A LITTLE BIT
ABOUT THE CASE.
MR. DUNN SAYS, HE HAD A
CONCEALED WEAPONS PERMIT.
HE TOOK, WE KNOW, THE GUN OUT OF
THE GLOVE COMPARTMENT, FIRED
EIGHT SHOTS INTO THE CAR AND HIS
ATTORNEY, FIRST ATTORNEY, HE'S
NOW SWAPPED ATTORNEYS SAID THEY
MIGHT FOCUS ON THE STAND YOUR
GROUND LAW AND MR. PHILLIPS YOU
CAN JUMP IN IF YOU FEEL LIKE
THIS IS A QUESTION THAT NEEDS TO
GO TO YOU.
HERE IS WHAT THE FIRST ATTORNEY
HAS SAID ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
THAT NIGHT.
LET'S PLAY THAT.
>> KILL THAT MOTHER [ BLEEP ],
YOU DEAD [ BLEEP ], AND HE SEES
THAT MUCH OF A SHOTGUN COMING UP
OVER THE RIM OF THE SUV, WHICH
IS UP HIGHER THAN HIS JETTA AND
ALL HE SEES ARE HEAVILY TINTED
FRONT WINDOWS THAT ARE UP, AND
THE BACK WINDOWS THAT ARE DOWN
AND THE CAR HAS AT LEAST FOUR
BLACK MEN IN IT, AND HE DOESN'T
KNOW HOW OLD ANYBODY IS, HE
DOESN'T KNOW ANYTHING, BUT HE
KNOWS A SHOTGUN WHEN HE SEES
ONE.
>> SO THAT'S HER EXPLANATION OF
WHAT HAPPENED.
IS THIS CASE ABOUT RACE?
IS THIS CASE ABOUT LOUD MUSIC?
WHAT IS THIS CASE REALLY ABOUT,
DO YOU THINK?
>> IT'S ABOUT LOUD MUSIC AND
IT'S ALSO ABOUT ANGER, ABOUT
HAVING A CONCEALED WEAPON IN
YOUR CAR, KNOWING YOU HAVE IT
AND FEEL BOLD ENOUGH TO USE IT
BECAUSE YOU'RE BEING SHIELDED IN
THE STATE OF FLORIDA, THEY TELL
YOU IF YOU HAVE A CONCEALED
WEAPON THESE ARE SOME OF THE
THINGS YOU CAN DO IF YOU FEEL
YOU'RE THREATENED IN ANY WAY,
THEN YOU ARE ALLOWED TO USE YOUR
WEAPON, SO HE WAS ANGRY, AND HE
HEARD LOUD MUSIC, OF COURSE YOU
GOT 17-YEAR-OLDS, THEY DON'T DO
WHAT YOU SAY IF YOU'RE IN A
PUBLIC PLACE.
YOU'RE NOT THEIR PARENT AND HE
DECIDED THAT, WELL, YOU KNOW
WHAT?
IF YOU DON'T TURN THE MUSIC DOWN
I'M GOING TO TAKE MY WEAPON OUT
AND SHOOT AT THE CAR AT LEAST
EIGHT TIMES AT THE CAR IN A GAS
STATION.
>> THE STAND YOUR GROUND LAW
SAYS YOU'RE JUSTIFIED TO USE
DEADLY FORCE IF YOU REASONABLY
BELIEVE THAT SUCH FORCE IS
NECESSARY TO PREVENT EMINENT
DEATH OR GREAT BODILY HARM TO
YOURSELF.
YOU WERE GOING TO SAY?
>> IF IT IS ABOUT RACE FOR MR.
DUNN HE'S THE ONLY ONE THAT
KNOWS THAT.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO USE THAT,
BECAUSE THAT DOESN'T JUSTIFY
ANYTHING THAT HAS HAPPENED FOR
JORDAN, IT DOESN'T JUSTIFY
TRAYVON MARTIN, IT DOESN'T
JUSTIFY ANYTHING THAT HAPPENS
FOR ANYONE ELSE THAT FALLS
VICTIM UNDER THIS LAW.
IT JUST DOESN'T.
SO HE'S THE ONLY ONE WHO
UNDERSTANDS AND KNOWS WHERE HE
WAS AND WHAT WAS IN HIS HEART AT
THAT TIME, AND HE HAS TO DEAL
WITH THAT.
>> DID YOU WORRY ABOUT JORDAN
WHEN THE TRAYVON MARTIN CASE
HAPPENED?
I'VE HAD SO MANY PARENTS SAY TO
ME --
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> OH MY GOD THAT COULD HAVE
BEEN MY KID.
>> ABSOLUTELY, YOU THINK ABOUT
THAT ALL THE TIME.
AS WE'VE SAID BEFORE WHEN YOUR
CHILDREN GROW UP AND GO ON, YOU
HAVE TO GIVE THEM A FREEDOM,
CHANCE AND OPPORTUNITY TO BE WHO
THEY ARE AND THEY MAKE FRIEND
AND DO THINGS, THERE'S ALWAYS
THE UNDERCURRENT, ALWAYS A
LITTLE BIT OF THAT FEAR THAT
YOU'RE CONCERNED BECAUSE YOU
CAN'T BE THERE WITH THEM, YOU
CAN'T HOLD THEIR HAND ANYMORE.
YOU'VE TRAINED THEM AND YOU'VE
DONE EVERYTHING THAT YOU CAN DO
BUT THEY DO HAVE TO GO OUT IN
THE WORLD.
YOU DO YOUR BEST THAT YOU CAN TO
PROTECT THEM.
>> SOLEDAD I'D LIKE TO REALLY
SAY THAT I JUST WANT THE
COMMUNITY AND THE WORLD, AMERICA
TO KNOW THAT WHEN YOU ALLOW
PEOPLE UNDER THIS SHIELD STAND
YOUR GROUND YOU'RE PUTTING IN
JEOPARDY YOUR KIDS THAT HAVE
NOTHING TO DO WITH THE TWO
PEOPLE THAT ARE FACING EACH
OTHER.
YOU HAVE PEOPLE, THE KIDS ARE
PLAYING HOP SCOTCH, KIDS ARE
JUMPING ROPE, RIDING BIKES, YOUR
NEPHEW, YOUR NIECE AND TWO
PEOPLE DECIDE TO DRAW DOWN ON
EACH OTHER, THEY'RE GOING TO HIT
ANYTHING THAT'S IN THE WAY, SO
AMERICA HAS TO KNOW THAT IT'S
NOT JUST THE TWO PEOPLE
INVOLVED, IT'S THE PEOPLE THAT
HAVE NOTHING TO DO WITH THE
10-YEAR-OLD KID, THE 10-YEAR-OLD
GIRL, SOMEBODY'S NIECE,
SOMEBODY'S DAUGHTER, THAT
HAPPENED TO BE PLAYING NEAR THE
TWO PEOPLE THAT DECIDED TO DRAW
ON EACH OTHER.
>> IT'S UNCLEAR IF HE'S GOING TO
IN FACT USE THE STAND YOUR
GROUND LAW.
THE SECOND ATTORNEY THAT HAS
COME IN HAS NOT INDICATED THAT
EITHER WAY BUT WHAT WOULD YOU
LIKE TO SEE FOR HIM?
>> THAT'S THE PROBLEM WITH THE
STAND YOUR GROUND LAW, BASED
UPON A REASONABLE PERSON'S
STANDARD AND THE ONLY WITNESS TO
THE REASONABLE PERSON WHETHER
THAT PERSON WAS BEING REASONABLE
WAS NOW KILLED IN EVERY ONE OF
THESE CASES AND THAT'S A MAJOR
PROBLEM.
>> WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE TO SEE
HAPPEN?
MR. DUNN GOES TO COURT ON
MONDAY, ARRAIGNMENT.
>> WE HAVE ACTUALLY ALREADY
BEGUN TO FIGHT AGAINST THE STAND
YOUR GROUND LAWS.
WE'VE STARTED
WWW.WALKWITHJORDAN.COM AND ON
THAT SITE, YOU CAN GO AND SIGN
THE FEDERAL PETITION TO GO TO
WASHINGTON, WE'RE GOING TO
WASHINGTON TO MAKE AMENDS TO THE
FEDERAL STAND YOUR GROUND LAWS.
WE HAVE TO DO IT FEDERALLY
BECAUSE THAT MANDATES ALL THE
STATES TO TAKE A LOOK AT THIS,
NOT JUST THE STATE OF FLORIDA.
SO WE'VE ALREADY BEGUN THAT
WALK, WAL
WALK, WWW.WALKWITHJORDAN.COM.
WE ONLY NEED 25,000 SIGNATURES,
BY THE END OF THIS MONTH, FOR
WASHINGTON TO TAKE A LOOK AT IT.
>> THANK YOU FOR TALKING WITH US
THIS MORNING.
I KNOW THIS IS A TERRIBLE,
HORRIFIC THING TO HAVE TO
DISCUSS AND SOMETHING I'M SURE
AS A PARENT YOU CAN'T EVEN
IMAGINE.
>> YES, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> LUCIA McBATH, THANK YOU.
WE HAVE TO TAKE A SHORT BREAK
THIS MORNING.
AHEAD WE'RE GOING TO TALK ABOUT
A YOUNG JOURNALIST WHO VENTURES
INTO WAR TORN AFRICA AND PUTS
HIS LIFE ON THE LINE TO GET THE
TRUTH, THE NEW BOOK CALLED "A
WORLD MADE OF BLOOD" IT'S
INCREDIBLE HE'LL BE HERE TO
DISCUSS THAT COMING UP NEXT.
initiated.
Neural speeds
increasing to 4G LTE.
Brain upgrading to a quad-core
processor.
Predictive intelligence
with Google Now complete.
Introducing DROID DNA by HTC.
It's not an upgrade
to your phone.
It's an upgrade to yourself.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAND.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
TIME FOR CITI PRICE REWIND.
BECAUSE YOUR DAUGHTER REALLY
WANTS THAT PINK CASTLE THING.
AND YOU REALLY DON'T WANT
TO PAY MORE THAN YOU HAVE TO.
ONLY CITI PRICE REWIND
AUTOMATICALLY SEARCHES
FOR THE LOWEST PRICE.
AND IF IT FINDS ONE, YOU GET
REFUNDED THE DIFFERENCE.
JUST USE YOUR CITI CARD
AND REGISTER YOUR PURCHASE
ONLINE.
HAVE A SUPER SPARKLY DAY!
OK.
[ Male Announcer ] NOW ALL
YOU NEED IS A MAGIC CARRIAGE.
CITI PRICE REWIND.
START SAVING
AT CITI.COM/PRICEREWIND.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
SEBASTIAN JUNGER IS BETTER KNOWN
FOR BEING OUT IN THE FIELD,
FACING DANGER, WRITING ABOUT IT.
HE'S A BEST SELLING BOOK LIKE
"THE PERFECT STORM" "WAR" AND
HIS LATEST WORK OF FICTION IS AN
eBOOK CALLED "THE WORLD MADE OF
BLOOD" AND TELLS THE STORY OF A
YOUNG AMERICAN JOURNALIST TRYING
TO SURVIVE HIS LATEST ASSIGNMENT
WHICH IS A WAR-TORN COUNTRY IN
AFRICA.
TALK TO ME A LITTLE BIT ABOUT
WHY YOU DECIDED TO WRITE THIS
STORY AND PUT IT OUT AS AN eBOOK
AND ALSO SOME OF THE REALLY
WHAT'S BEHIND SOME OF THE OTHER
PROJECTS YOU'RE REALLY
PASSIONATE ABOUT, HELPING
JOURNALISTS LIKE THE GUYS YOU
TALK ABOUT IN THE STORY.
>> I'VE ALWAYS BEEN A
JOURNALIST, COVERED A LOT OF
CIVIL WARS AS A JOURNALIST AND
AFTER SIERRA LEONE WAS MY FIRST
CIVIL WAR IN AFRICA, IT WAS
INCREDIBLY TERRIFYING.
I WAS AT A SITUATION AT A
CHECKPOINT WE WERE STOPPED BY
REBEL FORCES, STEPPED OUT OF THE
JUNGLE AND STOPPED US AT
GUNPOINT AND FOR ABOUT 15
MINUTES IT SEEMED LIKE THEY WERE
GOING TO KILL EVERYBODY.
I SPENT 15 MINUTES TRYING TO GET
MYSELF READY FOR THAT.
IT DIDN'T HAPPEN OBVIOUSLY.
I WROTE MY STORY AND SEVERAL
YEARS LATER I KEPT THINK BEING
THAT REALLY TRAUMATIC EPISODE
AND THOUGHT I WANT TO WRITE A
PIECE OF FICTION THAT GOES TO
WHAT HAPPENED WITH ME AND KEEPS
GOING, AND HOW WOULD I REACT,
HOW WOULD PEOPLE REACT AND SO
THAT WAS WHY I CAME TO WRITE
FICTION.
IT'S NOT SOMETHING MOST
JOURNALISTS DO BUT IT WAS AN
INTERESTING EXPERIENCE.
IT'S A SHORT STORY AND I PUT IT
ONLINE BECAUSE I WROTE THIS IN
'04 BUT NOW THAT'S HOW YOU REACH
PEOPLE IS ONLINE, IT'S ON
BYLINER AND WE'RE GETTING AN
INCREDIBLE RESPONSE.
PEOPLE ARE REALLY READING IT.
IT GOES TO THE DANGERS OF THE
JOB.
PEOPLE IN THE LAST YEAR MORE
JOURNALISTS HAVE BEEN KILLED
THIS PAST YEAR THAN SEVERAL
PREVIOUS YEARS COMBINED.
IT'S INCREDIBLY DANGEROUS NOW.
>> ESPECIALLY FOR THE
FREELANCERS.
WE ALL GET IN, IF YOU WORK FOR
CNN WE GO THROUGH THIS TRAINING
IF YOU'RE GOING TO BE IN A WAR
ZONE.
IF YOU'RE A FREELANCER YOU SHOW
UP WITH A BACKPACK AND HAVE TO
NAVIGATE AND LEARN AS YOU GO,
TERRIBLY DANGEROUS.
>> THE FIRST WAR I WAS IN, IN
BOSNIA AND '93, WENT THERE WITH
A BACKPACK, SLEEPING BAG AND
NOTEBOOKS.
THAT'S HOW I BROKE IN.
I DIDN'T HAVE AN ASSIGNMENT.
IN THE ARAB SPRING IT'S WIDE
OPEN FOR THAT OPPORTUNITY FOR
YOUNG PEOPLE AND THAT'S WHY THE
MORTALITY RATES SORE HIGH.
I STARTED AN ORGANIZATION CALLED
REPORTS INSTRUCTED IN SAVING
COLLEAGUES.
>> RISC.
>> TO PROVIDE FREE COMBAT
MEDICAL TRAINING TO FREELANCE
WAR REPORTERS.
I HAD A GOOD FRIEND TIM HEA
HETHERRINGTON, BUT HE JUST BLED
OUT.
HAD I BEEN THERE I WOULD HAVE
WATCHED HIM DIE, COULDN'T HELP
HIM.
I STARTED AA TRAINING PROGRAM,
THREE SESSION ACE YEAR TO TRAIN
FREELANCE WAR REPORTERS HOW TO
SAVE LIVES.
>> IT'S AMAZING HOW MANY THINGS
DO YOU IN TERMS OF NONPROFITS
AND THINGS AFTER STORIES THAT
HAVE TOUCHED YOU.
THIS IS NOT THE FIRST THING
YOU'VE DONE "THE PERFECT STORM"
YOU WERE MOVED TO MAKING A
DIFFERENCE IN ADDITION TO BEING
THE REPORTER AROUND IT.
IS THAT A WAY TO GET YOUR HEAD
AROUND ALL OF THE THINGS YOU SEE
AND DEAL WITH?
>> JOURNALISTS HAVE TO STAY OUT
OF THE STORY AND IF IT'S A
PAINFUL STORY THERE'S A MORAL
ANGUISH THERE.
NON-PROFITS ARE ONE WAY TO DEAL
WITH THE ANGUISH.
>> THANKS FOR TALKING ABOUT IT
WITH US.
THE eBOOK IS CALLED "A WORLD
MADE OF BLOOD."
SEBASTIAN, THANKS.
WE HAVE TO TAKE A SHORT BREAK.
>>> THE NEW U.S. MOVIE, WE TALK
TO AIDAN QUINN ABOUT
"ALLEGIANCE."
♪
(Announcer) When Subaru owners
look in the mirror,
they see more than themselves.
So we celebrate our year-end
with the "share the love" event.
Get a great deal on a new Subaru
and 250 dollars goes to your
choice of five charities.
By the end of this, our fifth
year,
our total can reach almost 25
million dollars.
It's a nice reflection on us
all.
Now through January 2nd.
THERE'S A HEALTH COMPANY THAT
CAN HELP YOU STAY THAT WAY.
WHAT'S HEALTHIER THAN THAT?
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
>>> IN 2004, NATIONAL GUARD
TROOPS WERE SENT TO IRAQ.
THOUSANDS OF MEN AND WOMEN WERE
FACING A YEAR OF COMBAT IN A
FOREIGN COUNTRY.
NEW FILM CALLED "ALLEGIANCE"
AIDAN QUINN PLAYS A BATTALION
COMMANDER WHO HAS TO PREPARE A
PART-TIME UNIT FOR COMBAT.
>> GENTLEMEN, THE DEPLOYMENT
ORDER IS OUT AND I'VE INSTRUCTED
THE SERGEANT MAJOR TO LOCK DOWN
THE BASE.
IN LESS THAN 48 HOURS, WE WILL
BE INSIDE ONE OF THE MOST
DANGEROUS COMBAT ZONES IN THE
WORLD.
>> THE FILM EXPLORES ISSUES OF
LOYALTY VERSUS DUTY AND IS
RESONATING IS VETERANS.
AIDAN QUINN NICE TO HAVE YOU
HERE.
>> NICE TO BE HERE.
>> ALLEGIANCE IS A MILITARY FILM
BUT IT ISN'T JUST FOR PEOPLE
INTERESTED IN THE MILITARY.
>> I JUST LOVED THE SCRIPT, THE
CHARACTERS.
THE GENTLEMAN, THE YOUNG MAN
THAT WROTE IT AND DIRECTED IT
DID A PHENOMENAL JOB AND TALKING
TO HIM, HE CONVINCED ME THAT HE
WAS GOING TO DO A GOOD JOB AND
INDEED HE DID.
>> HE'S A VETERAN AND HE
SURROUNDED HIMSELF THE ENTIRE
MOVIE, PEOPLE FUNDING IT AND
HELPING OUT ON IT WERE ALL
VETERANS.
WHAT KIND OF EXPERTISE DO YOU
THINK THEY BROUGHT TO MAKE IT
BETTER AND MORE REALISTIC?
>> YOU SEE A TREMENDOUS AMOUNT
OF EXPERTISE IN ALL THE
CHARACTERS, WHETHER IT'S, YOU
KNOW, THEY DO GREAT WORK, THEY
WERE TRAINED BY NAVY S.E.A.L.s
AND PEOPLE THAT WERE IN THE
MILITARY, WE HAD MILITARY ALWAYS
THERE, SO THEY JUST MADE SURE
THEY KEPT IT REAL.
>> IS IT A TRUE STORY?
>> I THINK IT'S BASED ON SOME OF
THE THINGS THAT HAPPENED TO THE
DIRECTOR.
I DON'T KNOW HOW MUCH OF IT IS
ACTUALLY TRUE, BUT IT'S BASED ON
A LOT OF THINGS THAT HAPPENED TO
MIKE CONNORS, THE DIRECTOR.
>> IT'S THE STORY OF ALLEGIANCE,
WHEN A FELLOW SOLDIER HAS TO GO
AWOL BECAUSE HE'S TRYING TO SEE
HIS SON WHO IS DYING AND OF
COURSE HE'S A PART-TIME SOLDIER
WHO NOW SUDDENLY HAS BECOME A
FULL TIME SOLDIER IN ANOTHER
COUNTRY.
I WANT TO SHOW A LITTLE CLIP OF
THAT.
>> DO YOU HONESTLY THINK I WANT
TO LET YOU WALK OUT OF HERE
WITHOUT EVEN A SLAP ON THE
WRIST?
HELL NO!
BUT THESE ARE THE DECISIONS I
HAVE TO MAKE FOR THE GOOD OF THE
UNIT.
FOR THE GOOD OF THE MEN.
THAT'S ALL, LIEUTENANT.
>> DO YOU THINK WE'RE SEEING
MORE MOVIES OUT OF HOLLYWOOD ON
THE MILITARY?
>> I DON'T THINK SO.
I THINK HOLLYWOOD IS VERY AFRAID
OF ANY MILITARY FILMS BECAUSE
THEY'RE TOUGH FOR THE AUDIENCE
BECAUSE WE HAVE CONFLICTED
FEELINGS ABOUT OUR INVOLVEMENT
IN IRAQ AND AFGHANISTAN.
I THINK THE GREAT THING THAT HAS
CHANGED IS WE HAVE 100%, ALMOST
SEEMS LIKE 100% APPROVAL OF OUR
VETERANS, AND SUPPORT FOR OUR
VETERANS.
I KNOW THAT IS A HUGE
IMPROVEMENT.
>> RIGHT, SO WHERE THERE IS
CONFLICT IT'S NOT OVER THE
INDIVIDUALS.
>> RIGHT.
>> MOST PEOPLE LOOK AT THEM AS
HEROES REGARDLESS OF HOW THEY
FEEL ABOUT THE SPENDING OR THE
WAR ITSELF.
>> EXACTLY.
>> THIS FILM IS BEING RELEASED
FIRST ON VIDEO ON DEMAND.
>> UM-HUM.
>> THEN WILL GO INTO MOVIE
THEATERS WHICH SEEMS TO ME TO BE
A COMPLETE FLIP OF HOW IT USED
TO WORK.
>> RIGHT.
IT'S EXACTLY THE OPPOSITE OF HOW
IT USED TO WORK BUT NOW HOW IT'S
DONE ON GOOD LOW BUDGET FILMS.
THE IDEA IS TO GET WORD OF
MOUTH, GET IT TALKED ABOUT ON
THE INTERNET AND THEN YOU
RELEASE IT SO YOU'RE ACTUALLY
GETTING FREE, IF YOU WILL,
PUBLICITY BY GETTING PEOPLE
TALKING ABOUT IT ON THE
INTERNET, AND IT'S QUITE
SUCCESSFUL.
>> INTERESTING, GETTING ALL THE
PEOPLE WATCHING IT ON VIDEO ON
DEMAND TO BE YOUR MARKETERS TO
DRIVE PEOPLE TO GO THE THEATERS.
AIDAN QUINN, NICE TO HAVE YOU.
>> VERY NICE TO BE HERE THANK
YOU.
>> YOU BET.
THE MOVIE COMES OUT DECEMBER
28th IN NEW YORK, JANUARY 4th IN
LOS ANGELES.
WE'RE BACK IN A MOMENT.
they see more than themselves.
So we celebrate our year-end
with the "share the love" event.
Get a great deal on a new Subaru
and 250 dollars goes to your
choice of five charities.
By the end of this, our fifth
year,
our total can reach almost 25
million dollars.
It's a nice reflection on us
all.
Now through January 2nd.
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
♪
BECOMING
PART OF THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
TREES WILL TALK TO NETWORKS
WILL TALK TO SCIENTISTS
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE.
CARS WILL TALK TO ROAD SENSORS
WILL TALK TO STOPLIGHTS
ABOUT TRAFFIC EFFICIENCY.
THE AMBULANCE WILL TALK
TO PATIENT RECORDS
WILL TALK TO DOCTORS
ABOUT SAVING LIVES.
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
THE NEXT BIG THING?
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
♪
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
♪
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
>>> WILL CAIN WILL START US OFF
"THE END POINT."
>> SEBASTIAN WAS SAYING "WORLD
OF BLOOD" WAS INSPIRED BY 15
MINUTES IN SIERRA LEONE, I HOPE
COTELL US MORE HOW THE 15
MINUTES PLAYED OUT.
>> I WAS STANDING FACE-TO-FACE
WITH SOMEONE WHO WAS GOING TO,
SAID THEY WERE GOING TO KILL ME
AND OR SEEMED LIKE THEY WOULD
AND I TRIED TO GET MYSELF READY
AND THE MAIN THING, I DIDN'T
HAVE ANY GRAND THOUGHTS.
I FELT VERY BAD ABOUT MY FAMILY
AND I WAS WORRIED IT WAS GOING
TO HURT WAS PRETTY MUCH, IT WAS
PRETTY SIMPLE.
>> WHAT HAPPENED AT THE END?
OBVIOUSLY YOU'RE HERE TO TELL
THE TALE SO YOU SURVIVED IT.
WHAT HAPPENED?
>> THEY DIDN'T SHOOT.
THEY EVENTUALLY LET US GO AND I
DON'T KNOW WHY.
THERE WAS A LOT OF YELLING AND
THREATENING OF COCKING