E
RELIEVES PAIN FAST,
WITH NO ODOR.
SO ALL YOU NOTICE IS RELIEF.
ASPERCREME.
>>> NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, SMALL,
CLOSE-KNIT COMMUNITY, SWALLOWED
BY GRIEF THIS MORNING AFTER THE
UNIMAGINABLE LOSS OF 20 CHILDREN
AND 6 ADULTS, ALL KILLED INSIDE
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
TODAY THEY PREPARE TO BURY THE
FIRST OF THE VICTIMS.
>> WE WILL MOVE ON.
WE WILL NEVER FORGET.
WE WILL IN MANY WAYS BE MADE
STRONGER.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA VISITING
GRIEVING FAMILIES AND SHOWING
SUPPORT DURING AN EVENING VIGIL
SAYS WE MUST DO MORE.
>> WE CAN'T TOLERATE THIS
ANYMORE.
THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
AND TO END THEM, WE MUST CHANGE.
>> AND NOW WE LEARN MORE ABOUT
THE VICTIMS THAT UNFORGETTABLE
FRIDAY MORNING.
THE ULTIMATE QUESTION REMAINS,
WHY DID IT HAPPEN.
AND WE MAY NEVER, EVER GET AN
ANSWER TO THAT QUESTION, WHY.
WELCOME TO A SPECIAL EDITION OF
"STARTING POINT" FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
I'M JOINED BY "EARLY START"
CO-ANCHOR JOHN BERMAN.
TODAY, TWO 6-YEAR-OLD BOYS WILL
BE BURIED AND CHILDREN ACROSS
THE COUNTRY HEAD BACK TO SCHOOL.
JACK PINTO, A LITTLE GUY WHO
LOVED NEW YORK GIANTS.
AND NOAH POZNER, THE YOUNGEST OF
THE 26 VICTIMS WHO DIED ON
FRIDAY MORNING.
HE IS A TWIN.
HIS SISTER SURVIVED.
>> STILL DOESN'T KNOW HOW HER
TWIN BROTHER DIED.
PRESIDENT OBAMA HERE, TRYING TO
BRING COMFORT TO THE
INCONSOLABLE, PROMISED TO USE
HIS POWERS, EVERYTHING HE CAN DO
AS PRESIDENT TO END THIS KIND OF
MADNESS.
>> THIS IS OUR FIRST TASK.
CARING FOR OUR CHILDREN.
CAN WE TRULY SAY AS A NATION
THAT WE'RE MEETING OUR
OBLIGATIONS?
>> THREE AROUND.
>> COME DOWN NOW.
ONE, TWO, THREE, READY, AND GO.
♪ COME NOW ALL MY
>> WE'RE REMEMBERING THE FALLEN,
ALL OF THEM.
A LITTLE MORE ABOUT VICTIMS LIKE
THIS GIRL ARE YOU SEEING RIGHT
HERE, ANA MARQUEZ-GREENE, THIS
LITTLE GIRL WHO LOVED TO SING
AND WRITE LOVE LETTERS TO HER
PARENTS.
OF COURSE, AS WE FOCUS ON THE
VICTIMS THAT WILL BE OUR MAIN
FOCUS.
BUT WE TALK ABOUT THE SUSPECTED
SHOOTER, HOW POLICE SAY HE GOT
INTO THE SCHOOL AND WHY HE MAY
HAVE BEEN TARGETING THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL TO BEGIN
WITH.
>> WE START OFF TELLING YOU
ABOUT THE FIRST OF 20 FUNERALS
FOR CHILDREN.
SANDRA ENDO, TODAY WILL BE ONE
OF THE TOUGHEST DAYS, SANDRA, AS
THEY TRY TO PUT INTO WORDS, MAKE
SOME KIND OF SENSE OF THESE
FUNERALS OF THESE LITTLE BOYS.
>> ABSOLUTELY, SOLEDAD, THE PAIN
OF THIS COMMUNITY BEING FELT
ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
LAST NIGHT, PRESIDENT OBAMA
SPEAKING TO RESIDENTS HERE IN
NEWTOWN, OFFERED WORDS OF
COMFORT AND SUPPORT.
>> I COME TO OFFER THE LOVE AND
PRAYERS OF A NATION.
I AM VERY MINDFUL THAT MERE
WORDS CANNOT MATCH THE DEPTHS OF
YOUR SORROW, NOR CAN THEY HEAL
YOUR WOUNDED HEARTS.
I CAN ONLY HOPE IT HELPS FOR YOU
TO KNOW THAT YOU'RE NOT ALONE IN
YOUR GRIEF.
>> AND PRESIDENT OBAMA ALSO MET
WITH THE VICTIMS' FAMILY MEMBERS
AND LAST NIGHT A TWEET FROM
30-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER OF THE
SLAIN PRINCIPAL AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY TWEETED THIS.
MY MOM WOULD BE SO PROUD TO SEE
PRESIDENT OBAMA HOLDING HER
GRANDDAUGHTER, BUT NOT AS PROUD
AS I AM OF HER.
AND TODAY MARKS THE FIRST DAY OF
FUNERALS FOR THE DAYS TO COME.
THIS AFTERNOON, 6-YEAR-OLD NOAH
POZNER WILL BE LAID TO REST.
JUST TURNED 6 LAST MONTH,
SURVIVED BY HIS TWIN SISTER.
FAMILY MEMBERS SAY DO NOT KNOW
EXACTLY THE WAY HER BROTHER
DIED.
ALSO BEING BURIED TODAY,
6-YEAR-OLD JACK PINTO.
A HUGE SPORTS FAN AND ONE OF HIS
FAVORITE STARS WAS NEW YORK
GIANTS RECEIVER VICTOR CRUZ.
CRUZ ON THE FIELD THIS WEEKEND,
PAID TRIBUTE TO PINTO, WRITING
ON HIS GLOVE.
TODAY'S GAME IS FOR YOU, JACK.
SOLEDAD AND JOHN, BACK TO YOU.
>> SUCH A MOVING TRIBUTE FROM
VICTOR CRUZ AND THERE WERE TRICK
OUT
TRIBUTES ALL AROUND THE COUNTRY
FROM FOOTBALL TEAMS.
TODAY IS THE FIRST DAY OF
FUNERALS AND FOR KIDS IN
CONNECTICUT, THE FIRST DAY BACK
TO SCHOOL, BUT NOT YET IN
NEWTOWN.
I WANT TO KNOW WHAT ARE THE
PLANS FOR THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL ITSELF?
>> THAT'S RIGHT, JOHN.
ALL SCHOOLS IN NEWTOWN WILL BE
CLOSED TODAY.
THAT'S FOR STAFF TO BE ABLE TO
TALK TO EXPERTS, TO FIGURE OUT
HOW TO DEAL WITH STUDENTS IN
THIS AFTERMATH OF THE TRAGEDY,
AND TOMORROW CLASSES WILL RESUME
EXCEPT FOR AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
ACCOMMODATED BY A NEIGHBORING
SCHOOL IN A NEIGHBORING TOWN.
JOHN, AND SOLEDAD.
>> SOME OF THE KIDS WILL BE
GETTING BACK TO SCHOOL AS SOON
AS TOMORROW.
REALLY, REALLY QUICKLY.
>> I IMAGINE THE ROUTINE WOULD
BE BETTER THAN KEEPING THEM OUT
OF SCHOOL.
I UNDERSTAND THE IDEA OF PARENTS
NOT WANTING TO LET THEIR
CHILDREN GO ANYWHERE NEAR A
SCHOOL.
BUT FOR KIDS, GETTING BACK TO
ROUTINE MIGHT BE HELPFUL.
>> GETTING KIDS BACK TOGETHER
IMPORTANT.
>> AS THIS IS HAPPENING, POLICE
VEST DIVISION INTO THE MASINVES
SWING.
>> CONNECTICUT POLICE HAVE
CONFIRMED THE IDENTITY OF THE
GUNMAN, THE FACT THAT HE USED A
SE
SEMIAUTOMATIC ASSAULT WEAPON TO
BLAST HIS WAY THROUGH.
ALISON KOSIK HAS THE LATEST.
ALISON, GOOD MORNING.
>> GOOD MORNING, SOLEDAD.
WE'RE GETTING A CLOSER LOOK AT
WHERE THE GUNMAN LIVED WITH HIS
MOTHER NANCY, A VERY QUIET,
AFFLUENT NEIGHBORHOOD HERE IN
SANDY HOOK.
THE HOUSE IS A BIG HOUSE SITTING
ON TOP OF THE HILL.
EVEN A WREATH ABOVE THE FRONT
DOOR.
WE'RE ALSO LEARNING NEW DETAILS
OF HOW THE GUNMAN GOT INTO THE
SCHOOL, DESPITE THE FACT THAT
THE SCHOOL HAD SECURITY, THAT IT
LOCKED ITS DOORS AT 9:30, HAD TO
BE BUZZED INTO THE SCHOOL.
WE ARE LEARNING HOW MANY WEAPONS
HE ON HIM, HOW MUCH AMMUNITION
HE WAS CARRYING.
THE GUNMAN, ADAM LANZA, FIRED
DOZENS OF BULLETS, USING A
SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPON, USING A
PISTOL TO KILL HIMSELF.
>> THE WEAPON HAS BEEN
IDENTIFIED AS A BUSHMASTER AR-15
ASSAULT STYLE WEAPON.
HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINES, AND, IN
ADDITION, THE SUBJECT HAD A
GLOCK .10 MILLIMETER AND .9
MILLIMETER SIG SAUER.
ALL WEAPONS HAD ADDITIONAL
MAGAZINES.
>> A FOURTH WEAPON WAS FOUND IN
A CAR OUTSIDE THE SCHOOL.
WE ARE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE
SHOOTER'S ACTIVITIES IN THE
DAYS, WEEKS AND MONTHS LEADING
UP TO THE SECOND WORST MASS
SCHOOL SHOOTING IN U.S. HISTORY.
LANZA VISITED A GUN RANGE.
WE DO NOT KNOW WHERE OR WHEN.
AN ATF SPOKESPERSON SAYS HIS
MOTHER, NANCY LANZA, VISITED A
SHOOTING RANGE MULTIPLE TIMES.
HER SON ALSO KILLED HER.
AS FOR MOTIVE, AUTHORITIES ARE
STILL SEARCHING FOR ANSWERS.
>> WE'RE PLEASED WITH THE WORK
THAT'S BEEN DONE SO FAR.
I'M HOPING THAT HELPS ANSWER
THAT QUESTION.
WE'RE PLEASED WITH THE PROGRESS
THAT WE'RE MAKING.
THIS IS A VERY LONG, TEDIOUS
PROCESS.
>> AND FEDERAL AGENTS ARE
ESPECIALLY FOCUSING ON THE
WEAPONS THIS GUNMAN HAS,
SPECIFICALLY THEY ARE VISITING
GUN RANGES AND GUN DEALERS IN
THE AREA.
>> SOMETHING LIKE 400 GUN
DEALERS IN A FOUR-STATE AREA,
FOUR-COUNTY AREA AND SOMETHING
LIKE 30 GUN RANGES AS WELL.
APPRECIATE THE UPDATE.
MORE FROM ZORAIDA SAMBOLIN.
ZORAIDA REALLY FOCUSED ON THE
VICTIMS OF THIS TRAGEDY.
MORE TO UPDATE US ON.
ZORAI
ZORAIDA.
>> I DO, SOLEDAD.
I AM AT TREADWELL PARK.
BEHIND US IS A SOCCER FIELD.
WE'RE EXPECTING A PRESS
CONFERENCE AT 9:00.
WE'LL BRING THAT TO YOU.
BUT YOU HAVE TO WONDER, HOW MANY
OF THESE CHILDREN, THESE VICTIMS
AND FAMILY MEMBERS HAVE ACTUALLY
ENJOYED THIS PARK.
WE WANT TO FOCUS ON THOSE LITTLE
VICTIMS.
6-YEAR-OLD CHARLOTTE BACON LOVED
SCHOOL AND DRESSES.
WE'RE TOLD, HER HAIR A MASS OF
BEAUTIFUL RED CURLS.
WE ARE REMEMBERING HER THIS
MORNING.
AS WELL AS 7-YEAR-OLD DANIEL
BARDEN.
A BUDDING ATHLETE.
A MEMBER OF THE SWIM TEAM AND
AVID SOCCER PLAYER.
HE REALLY EARNED HIS RIPPED
JEANS AND TWO MISSING FRONT
TEETH.
OLIVIA ENGEL.
HER FAVORITE STUFFED ANIMAL WAS
A LAMB.
FAVORITE COLORS PINK AND PURPLE.
A GIRL SCOUT AND INVOLVED IN
MUSICAL THEATER.
SHE LOVED MATH AND LOVED
READING.
7-YEAR-OLD JOSEPHINE GAY LIKED
TO RIDE HER BIKE IN THE STREET
AND SET UP HER OWN LEMONADE
STAND EVERY SUMMER.
SHE LOVED THE COLOR PURPLE.
AND THE OPINION PAL PRINCIPAL O,
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, 47 YEARS OLD.
LIVED IN WOODBURY, CONNECTICUT,
WITH HER HUSBAND, TWO DAUGHTERS
AND THREE STEPDAUGHTERS.
THESE ARE JUST SOME OF THE
VICTIMS THAT WE WANT TO
INTRODUCE YOU TO.
THEIR MEMORIES BEING HONORED IN
THIS COMMUNITY AND ACROSS THE
COUNTRY.
LATER THIS MORNING, WE'LL BRING
YOU THE PROFILES OF THE REST OF
THOSE WHO LOST THEIR LIVES ON
FRIDAY.
SOLEDAD.
>> ZORAIDA, I'M SO GLAD YOU ARE
DOING THAT.
SO NICE TO LEARN MORE ABOUT THE
CHILDREN AND SOME OF THE
VICTIMS.
SOMETIMES WE SPEND SO MUCH TIME
ON THE SUSPECT AND ALL THE
INVESTIGATION AROUND THE
SUSPECT.
SO MUCH NICER TO FOCUS ON THOSE
WHOSE LIVES SHOULD BE
REMEMBERED.
WE SHOULD BRING IN PASTOR ROCKY
VEACH.
NICE TO HAVE YOU WITH US.
>> THANK YOU.
>> YOU WERE IN DENVER WHEN
COLUMBINE HAPPENED.
ARE YOU A PASTOR HERE, FATHER OF
FIVE AS WELL.
WHAT HAVE YOU LEARNED FROM
LIVING THROUGH THE COLUMBINE
EXPERIENCE THAT ARE YOU NOW ABLE
TO APPLY HERE AND YOU CAN HELP
THE PEOPLE THAT ARE YOU
PASTORING?
>> I THINK MAYBE JUST THE
GENERAL EXPERIENCE OF GOING
THROUGH IT, UNDERSTANDING HOW IT
AFFECTS PEOPLE, HOW IT AFFECTS
THE COMMUNITY AND TRYING TO BE
THERE FOR PEOPLE IN THE MIDST OF
THAT AGAIN.
JUST HAVING GONE THROUGH IT, I
THINK REALLY THAT'S THE ONLY
THING.
I DON'T THINK YOU CAN BE
PREPARED FOR IT, ESPECIALLY TO
HAPPEN A SECOND TIME.
VERY SHOCKING STILL.
>> I BET.
YOU HAVE BEEN HOLDING VIGILS.
WHAT DO YOU TELL PEOPLE?
AS A PASTOR, I'M SURE -- AS
REPORTERS WE ASK THIS ALL THE
TIME.
WHY?
THIS CANNOT BE GOD'S PLAN.
THIS CANNOT BE.
THIS IS JUST EVIL OVER GOOD.
>> IT'S NOT GOD'S PLAN.
EVIL HAS A PERSONA BEHIND IT,
THERE IS A DEVIL.
IF YOU ARE CHRISTIAN, YOU HAVE
TO BELIEVE THAT.
WE TRY TO APPROACH IT FROM THE
UNSEEN REALM.
THERE ARE SOMETIMES THINGS GOING
ON IN THE UNSEEN REALM THAT IS
SEEN IN THE SCEEEN REALM.
THAT'S WHY WE PRAY.
>> THIS COMMUNITY DOESN'T WANT
TO BE DEFINED BY THIS TRAGEDY.
HOW DO YOU DO THAT?
>> MY JOB, HELPING THEM GET IN
TOUCH WITH THE LORD, GET IN
TOUCH WITH GOD, AND THEN LET THE
LORD BRING THE LIVES OF THE
PEOPLE TOUCHED HERE, AFFECTED
HERE, WHATEVER HEMENTS TO DO IN
THIS TOWN.
MY JOB IS SIMPLE REALLY.
GET PEOPLE TO PRAY.
SOMETIMES PEOPLE HAVE A HARD
TIME BELIEVING IN GOD OR
SEEING -- UNDERSTANDING WHY THIS
HAPPENED.
SO WE TRY TO TELL OUR
PARISHIONERS AND OTHER PEOPLE,
WHY DON'T WE PRAY.
IF WE DON'T BELIEVE NOW, LET'S
PRETEND LIKE WE DO IN PRAYER
UNTIL WE DO.
LET THE LORD HAVE HIS HAND IN
NEWTOWN.
>> WHAT WAS THE MOST HELPFUL
THING FOR THE PEOPLE IN
COLUMBI
COLUMBINE, TRYING TO MAKE SENSE
OF A SENSELESS TRAGEDY, MUCH AS
THEY ARE TRYING TO FIGURE IT OUT
HERE?
>> GOOD LEADERSHIP IN THE
COMMUNITY WAS SEEN THERE, IN ALL
OF THE SAME ASPECTS AS IT'S SEEN
THERE.
I THINK THE CHURCHES CAME
TOGETHER, WORKED TOGETHER FOR
ALL OF THE PEOPLE.
WE ARE CERTAINLY TRYING TO DO
THAT.
IF WE CAN WORK TOGETHER, THINK
WE'LL SEE A GOOD OUTCOME.
>> PASTOR ROCKY VEACH,E
APPRECIATE YOUR TIME THIS
MORNING.
>> YOU'RE WELCOME.
>>> THE SHOOTINGS IN NEWTOWN
HAVE REIGNITED THE GUN CONTROL
DEBATE.
WE'LL HEAR FROM A CHILDREN'S
HEALTH EXPERT ON THE IMPORTANCE
OF IMPROVING SAFETY AT SCHOOLS.
AFTER THE MASSACRE AT VIRGINIA
TECH, WHAT HAS BEEN ACCOMPLISHED
BETWEEN THEN AND NOW.
>> WE'LL LEAVE YOU WITH ONE OF
THE MOST MOVING THINGS I HAVE
SEEN ON TELEVISION, CERTAINLY
LATE NIGHT CHILDREN IN YEARS.
THE NEW YORK CHILDREN'S CHORUS
SINGING "SILENT NIGHT" IN
TRIBUTE TO THE VICTIMS IN THIS
COMMUNITY ON "SATURDAY LIGHT
LIVE."
♪ HOLY INFANT SO TENDER AND MILD
SLEEP IN HEAVEN LY PEACE SLEEP N
HEAVENLY PEACE ♪
is it really 100 calories?
Let me put you on webcan...
...lean roasted chicken...
and a creamy broth
Mmm
I can still see you.
[ Male announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
PLAYS A KEY ROLE
THROUGHOUT OUR LIVES.
One A Day Men's 50+
IS A COMPLETE MULTIVITAMIN
DESIGNED FOR MEN'S HEALTH
CONCERNS AS WE AGE.
IT HAS 7 ANTIOXIDANTS
TO SUPPORT CELL HEALTH.
One A Day Men's 50+.
(Announcer) When Subaru owners
Tlook in the mirror,TH.
they see more than themselves.
So we celebrate our year-end
with the "share the love" event.
Get a great deal on a new Subaru
and 250 dollars goes to your
choice of five charities.
By the end of this, our fifth
year,
our total can reach almost 25
million dollars.
It's a nice reflection on us
all.
Now through January 2nd.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
AS A NATION GRIEVES, EXPERTS ARE
EXAMINING HOW THE TRAGEDY AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
COULD HAVE BEEN PREVENTED.
>> DR. IRWIN REDLETTER, HEAD OF
COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY'S CENTER FOR
NATIONAL PREPAREDNESS.
HE JOINS US TO TALK ABOUT THIS.
ALSO PRESIDENT AND COFOUNDER OF
THE CHILDREN'S HEALTH FUND.
DOCTOR, WE TALK TO YOU NORMALLY
AFTER NATURAL DISASTERS.
YOU TALK ABOUT PREPAREDNESS FOR
ALL TYPES OF THINGS.
PREPARING FOR NATURAL DISASTER
IS ONE THING.
PREPARING FOR A SCHOOL SHOOTING
SEEMS TO BE A TOTALLY DIFFERENT
TYPE OF THING.
HOW DO YOU PREPARE?
>> IT IS INCREDIBLY DIFFICULT.
AND PARTICULARLY WHEN WE TALK
ABOUT ELEMENTARY SCHOOLCHILDREN.
HIGH SCHOOLS IS DIFFICULT
ENOUGH.
BUT IN ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS, THIS
IS COMPLETELY UNCHARTERED
TERRITORY.
PREPARING MEANS SEVERAL CONCRETE
STEPS THAT NEED TO BE TAKEN.
ONE IS VERY SERIOUS CONTROL OF
ENTRY INTO THE SCHOOLS AND THIS
HAS TO BE TAKEN VERY SERIOUSLY,
AND I THINK IN MOST SCHOOLS,
THEY ARE STARTING TO GET THAT
PICTURE, SECONDLY, THERE HAS TO
BE A VERY CLEAR PLAN ABOUT WHAT
TO DO IN THE EVENT OF A
SITUATION LIKE WE EXPERIENCED
HERE.
AND IN THIS SITUATION, ACTUALLY,
THE SCHOOL SEEMED TO BE REALLY
QUITE AMAZINGLY PREPARED IN
TERMS OF PEOPLE KNOWING WHAT
THEY NEEDED TO DO, HAVING A
LOCKDOWN PROCEDURE, AND HAVING
THE TEACHERS BE SO
EXTRAORDINARILY, REALLY HEROIC,
IN FOLLOWING THE PLAN, IN
FOLLOWING THEIR OWN JUDGMENT
ABOUT WHAT TO DO TO PROTECT AS
MANY KIDS AS POSSIBLE, AND UNDER
THE CIRCUMSTANCES, THEY DID
REALLY WELL.
BUT WE REALLY ARE IN UNCHARTERED
TERRITORY IN FIGURING OUT
EXACTLY HOW MUCH FURTHER WE NEED
TO DO.
PEOPLE ARE MENTIONING WHETHER WE
WANT SCHOOL ADMINISTRATORS BEING
ARMED, WHICH I DON'T AGREE WITH,
OR SHOULD THERE BE A POLICE
PRESENCE?
THERE ARE ALL SORTS OF ISSUES
NOW THAT WILL BE BROUGHT UP AND
A LOT OF DISCUSSION WILL TAKE
PLACE BEFORE WE COME TO A
CONCLUSION ABOUT WHAT NEEDS TO
BE DONE HERE.
>> YOU TESTIFIED IN THE WAKE OF
THE VIRGINIA TECH SHOOTINGS AND
TALKED ABOUT THE LOOPHOLES IN
THE GUN LAWS THAT ALLOWED A
GUNMAN THAT HAD A MENTAL ILLNESS
GET ACCESS TO WEAPONS.
AND YOU TALKED ABOUT NOT QUITE
LOOPHOLES, BUT OBSTACLES TO
GETTING HELP FOR PEOPLE WHO HAVE
PROBLEMS WITH MENTAL ILLNESS.
>> IT'S ACTUALLY A TERRIBLE
CHALLENGE.
OF ALL OF THE ISSUES WITH ACCESS
TO HEALTH CARE GENERALLY, ONE OF
THE MOST DIFFICULT THINGS TO GET
ACCESS TO IS COMPETENT MENTAL
HEALTH CARE WHEN YOU NEED IT.
AND FOR A LOT OF PEOPLE AND A
LOT OF PEOPLE IN AMERICA,
INCLUDING IN OUR OWN FAMILIES
AND NEIGHBORHOODS WHO HAVE ALL
SORTS OF ISSUES INVOLVING
PSYCHOLOGICAL OR BEHAVIORAL
PROBLEMS AND IT'S DIFFICULT,
THERE IS A SIGNIFICATIGMA ATTAC
YOU HAVE A PROBLEM ENOUGH TO SEE
SOMEBODY.
WE HAVE TO GET OVER THIS STIGMA.
AND WHEN WE NEED MENTAL HEALTH
PROVIDERS, IT'S NOT SO EASY TO
GET IT.
PARTICULARLY TRUE FOR PEOPLE WHO
AREN'T SO AFFLUENT.
WHO HAVE FINANCIAL TROUBLES, NOT
COVERED BY INSURANCE, SO FORTH.
WE HAVE SOMEBODY HONESTLY VERY
DISTURBED FOR A LONG PERIOD OF
TIME MOST LIKELY.
WE DON'T KNOW ALL OF THE DETAILS
YET.
WHO HAD THE RESOURCES IN THE
FAMILY NO QUESTION THE HELP
NEEDED.
BUT EVEN WHEN THAT'S THE CASE,
YOU HAVE TO TALK SOMEBODY INTO,
MAKE SURE THEY GET THE HELP THEY
NEED AND SOMETIMES THAT'S
IMPOSSIBLE TO DO.
WE HAVE TO REALLY FIGURE THAT
OUT AS WELL.
>> AND THE TWO THINGS INTERCEPT,
IT'S DEADLY.
WHO BECOMES UNHINGED, COMBINED
WITH EASY ACCESS TO WEAPONS.
>> AND A COUNTRY WITH 280
MILLION WEAPONS, AND A LOT OF
PEOPLE WITH ALL SORTS OF ISSUES
FROM A MENTAL HEALTH POINT OF
VIEW.
IT'S A TOXIC MIX.
AND IT'S VERY, VERY RARE, I HAD
SAY.
RARELY WE'LL SEE THIS HORRIBLE
OUTCOME, LIKE THE DISASTER WE
SAW IN CONNECTICUT A FEW DAYS
AGO.
>> DR. IRWIN REDLEDER, WE
APPRECIATE YOUR INSIGHT.
AHEAD, WE'LL MEET THE FAMILY OF
VICTORIA SOCIETY TO.
SHE IS A BRAVE TEACHER THAT DIED
SAVING MANY OF HER STUDENTS.
>> LIVE FROM NEWTOWN, BACK IN A
MOMENT.
[ Female Announcer ]
WHAT IF THE NEXT BIG THING,
ISN'T A THING AT ALL?
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
♪
BECOMING
PART OF THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
TREES WILL TALK TO NETWORKS
WILL TALK TO SCIENTISTS
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE.
CARS WILL TALK TO ROAD SENSORS
WILL TALK TO STOPLIGHTS
ABOUT TRAFFIC EFFICIENCY.
THE AMBULANCE WILL TALK
TO PATIENT RECORDS
WILL TALK TO DOCTORS
ABOUT SAVING LIVES.
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
THE NEXT BIG THING?
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
♪
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
♪
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
WITH SCOTTRADER
STREAMING QUOTES,
ANY WAY YOU WANT.
FULLY CUSTOMIZE IT
FOR YOUR TRADING PROCESS --
FROM THOUGHT TO TRADE,
ON EVERY SCREEN.
AND ALL IN REAL TIME.
WHICH MAKES IT JUST LIKE
HAVING YOUR OWN TRADING FLOOR,
RIGHT AT YOUR FINGERTIPS.
[ Rodger ] AT SCOTTRADE,
SEVEN DOLLAR TRADES
ARE JUST THE START.
TRY OUR
EASY-TO-USE
SCOTTRADER
STREAMING QUOTES.
IT'S ANOTHER REASON
MORE INVESTORS ARE SAYING...
[ All ]
I'M WITH SCOTTRADE.
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO "STARTING
POINT."
WE FOLLOW THE LATEST EVON THE
TRAGIC SCHOOL SHOOTING, WE'RE
FOLLOWING THE REST OF THE NEWS.
POLICE IN BRISTOL, CONNECTICUT,
ARRESTED SOMEONE FOR MAKING A
THREAT ONLINE AGAINST BRISTOL
HIGH SCHOOL.
BRISTOL IS ABOUT 30 MILES FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>>> LATER TODAY, THE STATE
DEPARTMENT IS ANDED TO GET THE
RESULTS OF AN INDEPENDENT REVIEW
BOARD ON THE TERROR ATTACK ON
THE U.S. MISSION IN BENGHAZI.
CONGRESS WILL RECEIVE THE REPORT
WEDNESDAY AND WILL BE BRIEFED BY
BOARD MEMBERS, HEARINGS AND
TESTIMONY IN THE HOUSE AND
SENATE START THURSDAY.
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON WAS SUPPOSED TO TESTIFY,
BUT SHE IS RECOVERING FROM A
FAINTING SPELL AND CONCUSSION.
SHE'LL BE WORKING FROM HOME.
>>> FOOTBALL TOOK A BACK SEAT ON
SUNDAY AS VICTOR CRUZ HONORED
ONE OF THE NEWTOWN SHOOTING
VICTIMS.
6-YEAR-OLD JACK PINTO.
JACK PINTO WAS A BIG, BIG FAN.
VICTOR TRUZ WROTE THE BOY'S NAME
ON HIS CLEATS AND GLOVES.
THE TEAM WORE DECALS ON THEIR
HELMETS FOR SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE FIRST GRADER MAY BE BURIED
IN CRUZ' NUMBER 80 JERSEY.
>>> POTENTIAL PROGRESS.
YESTERDAY A SOURCE FAMILY WITH
TALKS SAYS HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER HAS OFFERED TO EXTEND
THE DEBT LIMIT FOR A YEAR.
THAT IS THE AMOUNT THE
GOVERNMENT CAN LEGALLY BORROW.
IT STANDS AT 16$16.4 TRILLION.
RAISING IT REQUIRES AN ACT OF
CONGRESS WHICH REPUBLICANS
STRONGLY OPPOSE THIS ONE DAY
AFTER BOEHNER HAD OPPOSED HIGHER
TAX RATES FOR THOSE MAKING LESS
THAN $1 MILLION.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WANTS TO RAISE
TAXES FOR THOSE MAKING MORE THAN
$250,000.
ALL EYES REMAIN ON WHETHER
LAWMAKERS CAN SEAL A DEAL.
MANY ECONOMISTS, INCLUDING THE
FED CHIEF BEN BERNANKE, SAYS
THAT THIS COULD PULL THE NATION
BACK INTO RECESSION.
>> THAT WOULD BE AWFUL.
>>> STILL AHEAD ON OUR SPECIAL
EDITION OF "STARTING POINT" FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT THERE, ARE
SOME WHO SAY IF A TEACHER HAD
BEEN ARMED INSIDE THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, MAYBE THIS TRAGEDY COULD
HAVE BEEN PREVENTED, THAT IS
WHAT MANY GUN ADVOCATES HAS BEEN
SUGGESTING.
WE'LL TALK TO JOHN LOTT, WHO
THINK THAT CURRENT GUN LAWS
SHOULDN'T BE STRENGTHENED, THEY
SHOULD BE TOSSED OUT.
>>> PLUS, SHE DIED TRYING TO
PROTECT HER FIRST GRADE
STUDENTS.
WE'LL HEAR FROM VICTORIA SOTO'S
FAMILY, THAT UP NEXT ON
"STARTING POINT."
[ Male Announcer ] Alka-Seltzer
Plus PRESENTS THE Cold Truth.
I HAVE A COLD,
AND I TOOK NYQUIL,
BUT I'M STILL "STUBBED" UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT DOESN'T HAVE A DECONGESTANT.
NO WAY.
[ Male Announcer ] SORRY.
Alka-Seltzer Plus FIGHTS
YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A FAST ACTING
DECONGESTANT
TO RELIEVE YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
[ sighs ] THANKS!
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus.
♪ OH
WHAT A RELIEF IT IS! ♪
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
AND SAVE $1
VISIT Alka-Seltzer ON FACEBOOK.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a
Droid Incredible 4G LTE
by HTC for $49.99.
OMNIPOTENT OF OPPORTUNITY.
YOU KNOW HOW TO MIX BUSINESS...
WITH BUSINESS.
AND YOU...RENT FROM NATIONAL.
BECAUSE ONLY NATIONAL LETS YOU
CHOOSE ANY CAR IN THE AISLE.
AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE A FULL-SIZE
OR ABOVE.
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
I COULD GET USED TO THIS.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, YOU COULD BUSINESS PRO.
YES, YOU COULD.
GO NATIONAL. GO LIKE A PRO.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
YOU ARE WATCHING A SPECIAL
EDITION OF "STARTING POINT,"
COMING TO YOU FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THIS COMMUNITY WILL BURY TWO
6-YEAR-OLD BOYS TODAY, THE FIRST
OF MORE THAN TWO DOZEN FUNERALS
THAT THIS TOWN HAS TO ENDURE
AFTER FRIDAY'S MASSACRE AT THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE PLAN FOR SURVIVING STUDENTS
IS TO RETURN THEM TO CLASS AS
SOON AS POSSIBLE.
THEY WILL EVENTUALLY USE THE
CHALK HILL SCHOOL IN MONROE,
CONNECTICUT.
ABOUT SEVEN MILES FROM HERE.
>> PEOPLE NATIONWIDE ARE PAYING
RESPECTS WITH THE TWITTER
CAMPAIGN, URGING EVERYONE TO
WEAR GREEN AND WHITE TODAY.
THOSE WERE -- THOSE ARE SANDY
HOOK SCHOOL COLORS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WAS HERE,
CONSOLING GRIEF-STRICKEN PARENTS
AND BRINGING THEM A MESSAGE.
>> I COME TO OFFER THE LOVE AND
PRAYERS OF A NATION.
>> OUR MAIN FOCUS IS ON THE
VICTIMS, BUT WE ARE ALSO
LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE GUNMAN
TODAY.
A RELATIVE SAYS HE WAS PULLED
OUT OF THE NEWTOWN SCHOOL SYSTEM
BY HIS MOTHER, WHO WAS UNHAPPY
WITH THEIR PLANS FOR HER
TROUBLED SON.
>> AND YOU SAW A MOMENT AGO AS
THE LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS
WALKED INTO WHERE THEY WERE
HOLDING A VIGIL AND HOW PEOPLE
WERE CHEERING AND PATTING THEM
ON THE BACK.
SUCH AN EMOTIONAL MOMENT ON THE
VIGIL.
THEY HAVE BEEN A ROCK FOR THIS
COMMUNITY.
IMAGINE WHAT THEY HAVE SEEN IN
RESPONDING TO THAT ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
MUST BE A ON HORRIBLE THING FOR
THEM.
WE WANT TO TURN TO JOHN LOTT,
AUTHOR OF A BOOK CALLED "MORE
GUNS, LESS CRIME."
THAT'S HIS THEORY IN A NUTSHELL.
IF PEOPLE HAD MORE GUNS, THERE
WOULD BE MORE OPPORTUNITY FOR
SELF-DEFENSE, AND NOT ONLY WOULD
HE NOT LIKE TO SEE NEW GUN LAWS,
HE WOULD LIKE TO SEE CURRENT
LAWS TAKEN OFF THE BOOKS ALL
TOGETHER.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING ME.
ON FRIDAY, YOU WERE TALKING TO
PIERS AND WITH WOLF YESTERDAY,
AND YOU SAID IT'S TIME TO GET
RID OF GUN LAWS, THE TAKEAWAY
FOR YOU OF THIS MASSACRE AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IT'S TIME TO
GET RID OF GUN LAWS.
HOW DOES THAT POSSIBLY MAKE
SENSE TO YOU?
>> WELL, BECAUSE OF MY RESEARCH,
I'VEALKED TO DOZENS OF PEOPLE
WHO HAVE BEEN PRESENT AT
HORRIBLE EVENTS OVER TIME, AND
THE FEELING OF UTTER
HELPLESSNESS IS OVERWHELMING FOR
THESE INDIVIDUALS.
IT'S HARD TO THINK OF SOMETHING
MORE TERRIFYING THAN BEING
HELPLESS THERE WHEN ONE OF THESE
ATTACKS OCCURS.
THERE IS ONE COMMON FEATURE
ACROSS THE ATTACKS.
THE ONES THE PRESIDENT
MENTIONED, YOU GO BACK FROM 1950
AT LEAST ON, WITH ONLY ONE
EXCEPTION, ALL THE MULTIPLE
VICTIM PUBLIC SHOOTINGS HAVE
OCCURRED WHERE MORE THAN THREE
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN KILLED, HAVE
OCCURRED WHERE GUNS ARE BANNED.
WE TRY TO MAKE AN AREA SAFE BY
BANNING GUNS, BUT WHAT HAPPENS
IS, IT'S A LAW-ABIDING GOOD
CITIZENS WHO OBEY THE BAN AND
NOT THE CRIMINALS, AND RATHER
THAN MAKING --
>> BUT MORE THAN ONE THING IN
COMMON, RIGHT?
THERE IS ONE MORE THING IN
COMMON.
ONE THING IS COMMON IS THAT
SOMETHING HAS WEAPONS TOO, AND
THEY GO INTO A PLACE WHERE THEY
SHOULD NOT BE WITH A WEAPON.
SO I WOULD SAY IT'S NOT JUST ONE
THING IN COMMON.
THEY ARE ALSO ARMED OFTEN TO THE
HIT AND WITH AUTOMATIC WEAPONS
OR SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPONS.
>> NEVER WITH AUTOMATIC WEAPONS,
BUT WITH SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPONS,
SURE.
BUT HERE IS THE POINT.
WE ONLY HAVE TINY AREAS IN THE
UNITED STATES WHERE THAW ARE
COMPLETELY GUN-FREE ZONES, BUT
TIME AFTER TIME, THAT'S THE
PLACE THESE CRIMINALS GO.
TAKE THE AURORA, COLORADO, MOVIE
THEATER SHOOTINGS.
SEVEN MOVIE THEATERS WITHIN A
20-MINUTE CAR RIDE OF THE
KILLER'S APARTMENT.
ONLY ONE THAT BANNED GUNS.
HE DIDN'T GO TO THE MOVIE
THEATER CLOSEST TO HIS HOME.
THEATER THAT WAS LARGEST.
THE ONE HE WENT TO WAS THE ONLY
ONE THAT BANNED GUNS, AND YOU
SEE THAT --
>> LET ME STOP YOU THERE.
LET ME STOP YOU THERE.
HERE, AGAIN, A CASE WHERE
SOMEONE HAD A SEMI AUTOMATIC
RIFFLE, HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT HE
CHOSE THAT BECAUSE THEY BANNED
GUNS?
HAVE TALKED TO HIM?
I HAVE NOT SEEN ANYWHERE IN ANY
TRANSIT OF ANYTHING HE HAS SAID
THAT HE PICKED IT SPECIFICALLY
FOR THAT.
HE HAS NOT SPOKEN TO THE MEDIA.
HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT?
YOU DON'T KNOW THAT.
>> OKAY.
THERE ARE TWO POINTS.
ONE, I DON'T KNOW IN THIS
PARTICULAR CASE.
HE PICKS ONE OUT OF SEVEN.
ONLY ONE THERE, AND THE POINT
IS, EVERY TIME.
GO LOOK AT THE MALL SHOOTINGS,
MOST OF THE MALLS IN THE AREA
AREN'T POSTED AS GUN-FREE ZONES,
THE ONLY ONES THEY PICK ARE THE
ONES THAT ARE BANNED.
PICK THE COLUMBINE CASE.
YOU PROBABLY DON'T KNOW -- LET
ME GIVE YOU ONE PIECE OF
INFORMATION HERE.
TAKE THE COLUMBINE CASE.
DID YOU THANK DYLAN KLEBOLD WAS
WRITING STATE LEGISLATORS,
STRONGLY AGAINST IT,
PARTICULARLY UPSET A LAW THAT
WOULD ALLOW CONCEALED HANDGUNS
ON SCHOOL PROPERTY AND THE DAY
THE COLUMBINE ATTACK OCCURRED,
IT OCCURRED ON THE DAY OF FINAL
PASSAGE OF THE STATE CONCEALED
HANDGUN LAW.
>> BUT, LISTEN, WHY IS YOUR
TAKEAWAY.
>> THAT IS AT COLUMBINE.
>> WHY IS YOUR TAKEAWAY TO GET
RID OF GUN LAWS RATHER THAN
THERE ARE PEOPLE THAT SHOULD NOT
HAVE ACCESS TO WEAPONS.
IN THIS PARTICULAR CASE, WE KNOW
THAT THE INVESTIGATION IS JUST
AT THE BEGINNING STAGES, BUT WE
KNOW HE USED A SEMIAUTOMATIC
RIFLE TO BLOW OUT THE GLASS WALL
AT THE SCHOOL.
THE SECURITY IS USELESS.
WHY?
BECAUSE HE HAD A HIGH-VELOCITY,
MULTISHOT WITH MANY ROUNDS WITH
HIM TO ACCESS THE SCHOOL.
WHY WOULD YOU NOT SAY, THAT'S
EXACTLY THE KIND OF WEAPON THAT
SOMEONE SHOULD NOT BE ABLE TO
EASILY GET THEIR HANDS ON?
AND HE WAS ABLE EASILY TO GET
HIS HANDS ON IT.
IT WAS LEGALLY REGISTERED TO HIS
MOTHER.
WHY IS THAT NOT YOUR TAKEAWAY?
>> YOU KNOW WHAT COUNTRY HAD TWO
OF THE THREE WORST PUBLIC
SHOOTINGS PRIOR TO FRIDAY?
IT WAS GERMANY.
GERMANY HAD THREE OF THE FIVE
WORST PUBLIC SCHOOL SHOOTINGS IN
THE WORLD.
NOW, THEY HAVE EXTREMELY STRICT
GUN CONTROL LAWS.
YOU CAN'T GET SEMIAUTOMATIC
WEAPONS.
IT TAKES A YEAR TO GET A BOLT
ACTION LONG RIFLE THERE.
YET THEY HAS THE WORST RECORD
THAN WE HAVE HERE IN THE UNITED
STATES, EVEN WITH THIS ATTACK.
SO I --
>> I DON'T SEE HOW ANY OF THAT
BRINGS YOU TO THE DECISION THAT
THE ANSWER IS TO GET RID OF GUN
LAWS.
THE OTHER QUESTION I WOULD ASK
YOU --
>> BECAUSE THEY SERVE AS A
MAGNET FOR THESE ATTACKS.
>> OR -- OR A RATIONAL PERSON
COULD SAY -- OR A RATIONAL
PERSON COULD SAY THAT HAVING
ACCESS TO A HIGH-POWERED
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE IS
INAPPROPRIATE.
THAT THERE IS NO REASON TO GO
DEER HUNTING WITH THAT, NO
REASON TO HAVE ACCESS TO THAT.
THAT'S THE CONNECTION THAT THESE
KILLERS HAVE ACCESS TO THOSE
WEAPONS.
LET ME ASK YOU ANOTHER QUESTION.
>> NO, I WANT TO ANSWER THAT
THAT YOU JUST SAID.
NO, I DON'T ARGUE SECOND
AMENDMENT.
I ARGUE CRIME.
THAT'S WHAT I DO.
I WANT TO ANSWER YOUR QUESTION
HERE.
THESE GUNS ARE JUST LIKE ANY
HUNTING RIFLE.
THE INSIDE GUTS, THEY FIRE ONE
BULLET.
IN FACT, BUSHMASTER GUN THERE
IS -- WOULD BE THE EQUIVALENT OF
A RIFLE THAT WOULD BE USED FOR
HUNTING VERY SMALL GAME, LIKE
SQUIRRELS.
IT LOOKS DIFFERENT ON THE
OUTSIDE, BECAUSE SOME PEOPLE
LIKE TO HAVE GUNS THAT LOOK LIKE
MILITARY WEAPONS, BUT IT'S NOT.
IT'S LIKE ANY HUNTING RIFLE.
>> SIR, SIR --
>> IF YOU WANT TO BAN ALL
HUNTING RIFLES, THAT'S FINE.
>> SIR, IF YOU ARE TRYING TO
KILL A LARGE NUMBER OF PEOPLE IN
A MASSACRE, THAT'S THE KIND OF
GUN YOU GRAB.
>> A HUNTING RIFLE WOULD DO THE
SAME THING.
>> IF YOU COULD INFLICT AS MUCH
CARNAGE ON PEOPLE, THAT'S THE
KIND OF GUN YOU GRAB.
HOW YOU COULD SAY WE SHOULD HAVE
FEWER LAWS, NOT MORE, IT BOGGLES
THE MIND.
IF YOU WOULD COME AND TALK TO
THE PEOPLE IN THE TOWN HERE,
THEY WOULD BE STUNNED BY YOU.
>> UNFORTUNATELY, I TALKED TO
MULTIPLE PEOPLE THAT HAVE BEEN
VICTIMS OF PUBLIC SHOOTINGS.
GUNS ARE BENEFICIAL FOR
SELF-DEFENSE.
IF YOU HAD TWO CRIMINALS COMING
AT YOU, YOU DON'T WANT A GUN
THAT ONLY FIRES ONE SHOT LIKE
THAT.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO?
YOU CAN'T EVEN FIRE A WARNING
SHOT.
IF YOU MISS THE FIRST SHOT AND
YOU DON'T HAVE A SEMIAUTOMATIC
GUN, WHAT DO YOU DO FOR
SELF-DEFENSE AT THIS POINT?
>> AND IF YOU HAVE -- IF YOU
HAVE A MAN WHO SEEMS TO BE
TROUBLED AND HE IS ARMED WITH A
SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPON, A RIFLE,
THEN THERE IS A HIGH LIKELIHOOD
THAT IS HE GOING TO MASSACRE A
LOT OF PEOPLE IN ONE LOCATION,
SIR, IN A VERY SMALL AMOUNT OF
TIME.
WE COULD CONTINUE THIS DEBATE
FOR A LONG TIME, I APPRECIATE
YOU TALKING WITH ME THIS
MORNING, BUT I JUST -- I HAVE TO
SAY, YOUR POSITION -- YOUR
POSITION COMPLETELY BOGGLES ME,
HONESTLY.
I JUST DO NOT UNDERSTAND IT.
THANK YOU FOR TALKING WITH US.
>>> I WANT TO BRING IN DEEPAK
CHOPRA.
BECAUSE I GET SO FRUSTRATED AT
TIMES WHEN I HAVE THESE
CONVERSATIONS AND MANY PEOPLE
POINT BACK TO THE SECOND
AMENDME
AMENDMENT, WHICH WE SHOULD READ
FOR EVERYBODY, BECAUSE IT'S USED
OFTEN AS A POSITION.
>> REMEMBER, SOLEDAD, WHEN THE
SECOND AMENDMENT WAS WRITTEN,
PEOPLE HAD MUSKETS, IT TOOK 20
MINUTES TO LOAD ONE AND HALF THE
TIME THEY MISSED.
THE SECOND AMENDMENT WASN'T
WRITTEN FOR ASSAULT WEAPONS,
AMMUNITION, AND THE EASY
AVAILABILITY OF THESE GUNS OF
MASS DESTRUCTION OVER THE
INTERNET.
>> HERE IS WHAT IT SAYS.
A WELL-REGULATED MILITIA, BEING
NECESSARY FOR THE SECURITY OF
THE PEOPLE THE RIGHT TO KEEP AND
BEAR ARMS SHALL NOT BE INFRIN  D
INFRINGED.
IT DOESN'T MENTION ASSAULT
WEAPONS.
>> THERE WEREN'T ANY.
>> I GUESS RIGHT NOW PEOPLE SEEM
VERY FRUSTRATED AND ANGRY ABOUT
WHERE WE ARE IN IN COUNTRY IN
THE DEBATE OVER MENTAL HEALTH
AND WEAPONS.
KIND OF THE INTERSECTION OF
THOSE TWO THINGS.
I GET THE SENSE OFTEN WE WRING
OUR HANDS UNTIL THE NEXT
TRAGEDY, THERE MAY NOT BE
ANYTHING TANGIBLY DONE.
>> SEE, ONE SINGLE MENTALLY
UNSTABLE PERSON BROUGHT THE
WHOLE COUNTRY TO THIS STATE OF
DEEP SORROW, ANGUISH.
IF THAT DOESN'T GALVANIZE OUR
COLLECTIVE PSYCHE TO CHANGE
THESE LAWS, THEN WE ARE GOING TO
LIVE FOR THE NEXT HALF A CENTURY
IN A CULTURE OF VIOLENCE.
THERE IS NO OTHER COUNTRY, NO
OTHER ADVANCED COUNTRY --
>> PEOPLE COULD TICK OFF AND YOU
KNOW THIS WELL, NOT ONLY MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES, NOT ONLY EASY
ACCESS TO GUNS.
MOVIES, ABSOLUTELY GLORIFY
VIOLENCE, VIDEO GAMES SEEM TO BE
RELEVANT IN THIS CASE,
ESPECIALLY VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES,
AND EVERYBODY LIKES TO POINT --
>> ALL OF THAT IS PART OF THE
CONTEXT, BUT YOU CANNOT KILL ON
THE SCALE UNLESS HAVE YOU A GUN.
OH, PEOPLE KILL PEOPLE, NOT
GUNS, BUT PEOPLE USE GUNS TO
KILL.
YOU KNOW WE DO HAVE TO SLOWLY
CREATE A CULTURE OF KINDNESS AND
LOVE AND COMPASSION AND EMPATHY,
THAT'S WHAT A CIVIL SOCIETY
SHOULD BE DOING.
IN THE MEANWHILE, YOU HAVE TO
ACTUALLY GET RID OF THE ASSAULT
WEAPONS THAT ARE DIRECTLY
RESPONSIBLE FOR THE KILLING.
>> ALL RIGHT, DEPACK.
WE HAVE TO WRAP THIS UP.
WE HAVE A LOT MORE QUESTIONS.
NOT JUST ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
WITH THE GUNS AND THE VIOLENCE
IN OUR SOCIETY.
BUT ALSO HOW TO MOVE ON.
HOW TO FIN THE INNER PEACE TO
DEAL WITH THESE ISSUES.
WE LOOK FORWARD TO TALKING TO
MORE ON THAT.
>>> ZORAIDA SAMBOLIN, SHE HAS
MORE DETAILS ON THE VICTIMS OF
THE CRIME.
>> JOHN, DEEPAK CHOPRA SAYS THIS
BRINGS US DEEP SORROW AND
ANGUISH, AND AS I READ THIS AND
I'M ABOUT TO SHARE THIS, IT
ACTUALLY MADE ME SMILE.
WE WANT TO TALK ABOUT THE
VICTIMS THAT WERE LOST ON
FRIDAY.
REMEMBERING 6-YEAR-OLD DYLAN
HOCKLEY.
HE LOVED VIDEO GAMES, JUMPING ON
A TRAMPOLINE, WATCHING MOVIES
AND EATING GARLIC BREAD.
MADELINE HUH, SIX YEARS OLD.
A LITTLE GIRL WHO ALWAYS WORE
BRIGHT AND FLOWERY DRESSES.
WE'RE ALSO REMEMBERING
6-YEAR-OLD CATHERINE HUBBARD.
SHE LOVED ANIMALS AND IN LIEU OF
FLOWERS, HER FAMILY IS ASKING
FOR DONATIONS TO THE NEWTOWN
ANIMAL SHELTER.
CHASE KOWALSKI, HE HAD JUST
COMPLETED AND WON HIS FIRST MINI
TRIATHLON.
JESSE LEWIS, 6 YEARS OLD, LOVED
MATH AND RIDING HORSES AND
PLAYING AT HIS MOTHER'S FARM.
6-YEAR-OLD JAMES MATTIOLI, HE
WAS A HAPPY CHILD THAT WOULD
WAIT FOR THE SCHOOL BUS AT THE
BOTTOM OF THE FAMILY'S DRIVEWAY
WITH HIS DAD AND ANNE MARIE
MURPHY, MARRIED, MOTHER OF FOUR.
SHE IS DESCRIBED AS BEING
ARTISTIC AND HARD WORKING.
AND ANOTHER SANDY HOOK TEACHER,
27-YEAR-OLD VICKIE SOTO, MANY
REMEMBERED FOR HEROISM UNDER
FIRE.
SHE SPENT HER FINAL MOMENTS
SHIELDING HER STUDENTS FROM
HARM, HIDING THEM IN A CLOSET
BEFORE A GUNMAN ENTERED HER
CLASSROOM.
HER MOTHER IS NOT SURPRISED BY
HER DAUGHTER'S ACTIONS.
>> SHE WAS TRULY SELFLESS, SHE
WOULD NOT HESITATE TO THINK TO
SAVE ANYONE ELSE BEFORE HERSELF
AND ESPECIALLY CHILDREN.
SHE LOVED THEM MORE THAN LIFE
AND SHE -- SHE WOULD DEFINITELY
PUT HERSELF IN FRONT OF THEM ANY
DAY, ANY DAY FOR ANY REASON.
SO IT DOESN'T SURPRISE ANYBODY
THAT KNOWS VICKIE THAT SHE DID
THIS.
>> SOTO'S MOTHER SAYS TEACHING
WAS ALL VICKIE EVER WANTED TO
DO, SINCE THE AGE OF THREE
ACTUALLY.
TO FIND OUT HOW YOU CAN HELP
THOSE AFFECTED BY THE TRAGEDY,
GO TO CNN.COM/IMPACT.
THERE ARE A LOT OF OPTION THERE
FOR YOU, WAYS YOU CAN HELP AND
FEEL LIKE YOU'RE DOING
SOMETHING.
JOHN, SOLEDAD.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH, ZORAIDA.
SO NICE TO HEAR THE STORIES.
>>> ONE OF THE QUESTIONS WE'RE
ASKING, HOW DO YOU HELP CHILDREN
GRIEVE, UNDERSTANDING THE
TRAGEDY.
DR. SANJAY GUPTA, GETTING MIKED
UP RIGHT THERE.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT IN THIS A
MOMENT.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
IF YOU ARE ONE OF
THE MILLIONS OF MEN
WHO HAVE USED AndroGel 1%,
THERE'S BIG NEWS.
PRESENTING AndroGel 1.62%.
BOTH ARE USED TO TREAT MEN
WITH LOW TESTOSTERONE.
AndroGel 1.62%
IS FROM THE MAKERS
OF THE NUMBER ONE PRESCRIBED
TESTOSTERONE
REPLACEMENT THERAPY.
IT RAISES YOUR TESTOSTERONE
LEVELS, AND...
IS CONCENTRATED,
SO YOU COULD USE LESS GEL.
AND WITH AndroGel 1.62%,
YOU CAN SAVE
ON YOUR MONTHLY PRESCRIPTION.
[ Male Announcer ]
DOSING AND APPLICATION SITES
BETWEEN THESE PRODUCTS DIFFER.
WOMEN AND CHILDREN SHOULD AVOID
CONTACT WITH APPLICATION SITES.
DISCONTINUE AndroGel
AND CALL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU SEE UNEXPECTED SIGNS
OF EARLY PUBERTY IN A CHILD,
OR, SIGNS IN A WOMAN
WHICH MAY INCLUDE
CHANGES IN BODY HAIR
OR A LARGE INCREASE IN ACNE,
POSSIBLY DUE TO
ACCIDENTAL EXPOSURE.
MEN WITH BREAST CANCER
OR WHO HAVE OR MIGHT HAVE
PROSTATE CANCER,
AND WOMEN WHO ARE,
OR MAY BECOME PREGNANT
OR ARE BREAST FEEDING
SHOULD NOT USE AndroGel.
SERIOUS SIDE EFFECTS
INCLUDE WORSENING
OF AN ENLARGED PROSTATE,
POSSIBLE INCREASED RISK
OF PROSTATE CANCER,
LOWER SPERM COUNT,
SWELLING OF ANKLES, FEET,
OR BODY,
ENLARGED OR PAINFUL BREASTS,
PROBLEMS BREATHING
DURING SLEEP,
AND BLOOD CLOTS IN THE LEGS.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT YOUR MEDICAL CONDITIONS
AND MEDICATIONS,
ESPECIALLY INSULIN,
CORTICOSTEROIDS, OR MEDICINES
TO DECREASE BLOOD CLOTTING.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR TODAY
ABOUT AndroGel 1.62%
SO YOU CAN USE LESS GEL.
LOG ON NOW
TO AndroGelOffer.com
AND YOU COULD PAY AS LITTLE
AS TEN DOLLARS A MONTH
FOR AndroGel 1.62%.
WHAT ARE YOU WAITING FOR?
THIS IS BIG NEWS.
>>> ONE OF THE MOST DIFFICULT
THINGS MOVING FORWARD IN ANY
TRAGEDY, HOW TO EXPLAIN EXACTLY
WHAT HAS HAPPENED TO CHILDREN,
ESPECIALLY SINCE CHILDREN HAVE
BEEN THE VICTIMS IN THIS
PARTICULAR CRIME.
>> OH, YEAH.
YOU HAD TO EXPLAIN IT BOTH TO
THOSE WHO WITNESSED THE TRAGEDY
AND THOSE WHO MAY BE HEARING
ABOUT IT RIGHT NOW, ON THE
RADIO, IN TELEVISION, AT OTHER
KIDS IN SCHOOL.
WE'RE JOINED BY DR. SANJAY
GUPTA, WHO HAS BEEN LOOKING INTO
THIS THE PAST FEW DAYS.
WE TALKED YESTERDAY, SANJAY.
A QUESTION VERY PERSONAL TO ME.
I AM STRUGGLING HOW TO TALK TO
MY KIDS, WHETHER TO TALK TO MY
KIDS.
ARE THERE RIGHT ANSWERS HERE?
>> I THINK THE ANSWER OF TALKING
TO YOUR KIDS AS OPPOSED TO
IGNORING IT IS PROBABLY THE ONLY
RIGHT ANSWER.
AND ASSUMING THEY WILL FIND OUT.
I KNOW YOU BOTH HAVE CHILDREN.
YOU BOTH HAVE TWINS.
AND I HAVE A 7, 5, AND
3-YEAR-OLD.
MY 7-YEAR-OLD ALREADY KNEW ABOUT
IT I'M POSITIVE MY 5-YEAR-OLD
WILL LEARN ABOUT IT TODAY AND
WE'RE ALREADY PREPPING FOR THAT
CONVERSATION.
I THINK THAT THE IDEA THAT YOU
CHECK YOUR OWN FEELINGS FIRST,
IN MEDICINE, CHECK YOUR OWN
PULSE BEFORE GOING INTO A CODE,
IN THIS SITUATION, CHECKING YOUR
OWN FEELINGS.
DON'T OVERTALK TO YOUR CHILD.
THAT IS A CONSTANT CONCERN I'VE
BEEN HEARING.
YOU LET THEM TALK FIRST.
SEE WHAT THEY ARE SAYING, WHAT
THEY KNOW.
A LITTLE BIT ABOUT FEELINGS AND
AS APPROPRIATE, FILL IN DETAILS.
DON'T BE GRAPHIC, PROBABLY NOT
APPROPRIATE AT ANY AGE.
YOU HAVE TO HAVE THE
CONVERSATION.
>> WHAT DO YOU SAY, IS MY SCHOOL
SAFE?
MY KIDS TALKING ABOUT IT.
VERY UPSET.
I'VE BEEN GONE A COUPLE OF DAYS.
AND WALK IN THE DOOR, THEY ARE
HAPPY TO SEE YOU, AND THEN BURST
INTO TEARS, BECAUSE THIS IS VERY
UPSETTING.
>> YOU DON'T LIE.
EVERYONE SAYS THAT LOSS OF
INNOCENCE -- I REMEMBER,
SOLEDAD, WHEN WE WERE COVERING
SOME OF THE CONFLICTS, AND I
REMEMBER BEING IN A RED CROSS
TRUCK, AND THE RED CROSS TRUCK I
CAME UNDER FIRE, AND I REMEMBER
THINKING THE RULES HAVE CHANGED.
>> WHAT DO YOU SAY?
>> WHAT I SAID TO MY 7-YEAR-OLD,
THIS NEVER HAPPENED IN DADDY'S
SCHOOL, NEVER HAPPENED IN
MOMMY'S SCHOOL.
IT HAPPENED HERE OBVIOUSLY, BUT
WE'RE DOING EVERYTHING WE CAN TO
MAKE SURE IT WILL NEVER HAPPEN
TO YOU.
KIDS WILL SEE THROUGH IT IF YOU
MAKE FALSE PROMISES.
>> A WOMAN WROTE A FASCINATING
BLOG, SENT AROUND TWITTER.
AND IT SAYS I ADAM AM LANZA'S
MOTHER.
SHE WRITES ABOUT HER EXPERIENCE
WITH HER SON.
I LIVE WITH A SON WHO IS
MENTALLY ILL.
I LOVE MY SON, BUT HE TERRIFIES
ME.
WHEN I ASKED MY SON ABOUT SOCIAL
WORKERS WHAT I SHOULD DO, IF IS
HE IS IN THE SYSTEM, THERE WILL
BE A PAPER TRAIL.
NO ONE WILL PAY ATTENTION TO YOU
UNLESS HAVE YOU CHARGES.
I DON'T BELIEVE MY SON BELONGS
IN JAIL.
HE'S 13 YEARS OLD.
>> I FEEL STRONGLY ABOUT THIS.
I HAVE DONE A LOT OF REPORTING.
RIGHT NOW, SHORT OF GOING INTO
THE CRIMINAL JUSTICE SYSTEM,
WHICH YOU WILL GIVE YOUR KID A
RECORD, AND PARENTS, IT'S
OBVIOUSLY A TOUGH THING.
SHORT OF THAT, TO GET SOMEONE
IMPATIENT THERAPY, THEY HAVE TO
BE AN IMMINENT HARM TO
THEMSELVES OR OTHERS.
AND OVER AND OVER AGAIN, WE HEAR
THE FIRST TIME THEY SEE THAT
WHEN SOMETHING TRAGIC HAPPENS.
THERE WASN'T EVIDENCE OF
IMMINENT HARM TO THEMSELVES OR
OTHERS. A VERY, VERY HIGH
THRESHOLD.
THAT IS NOT PARITY.
YOU DON'T GO INTO THE DOCTOR FOR
A PHYSICAL ONLY WHEN YOU'RE
ABOUT TO DIE.
>> IF YOU HAVE A HEART ATTACK,
WE'LL SEE YOU.
>> WHEN PEOPLE TALK ABOUT MENTAL
HEALTH, YOU GUYS HAVE BEEN
TALKING ALL MORNING ABOUT IT.
THAT'S THE MANIFESTATION OF NOT
HAVING THINGS ON PAR.
>> WHAT THRESHOLD ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
>> RIGHT NOW IT HAS TO BE
IMMINENT HARM TO YOURSELF OR TO
OTHERS.
>> WHAT'S AN APPROPRIATE ONE?
>> WELL, IF SOMEONE HAS SYMPTOMS
OF MENTAL ILLNESS THAT ARE SHORT
OF THAT -- THERE'S ALL SORTS OF
DIFFERENT THINGS.
WE TALK ABOUT DEPRESSION.
THERE'S A WHOLE COMBINATION OF
THINGS, CHANGES IN APPETITE,
CHANGES IN SLEEPING, ALL THESE
TYPES OF THINGS THAT MAY SEEM
MINOR IN COMPARISON BUT ARE THE
PROGRESSION OF A MUCH MORE
SERIOUS ILLNESS.
>> THEN DOES A DOCTOR HAVE TO
REPORT THAT?
I HAVE A PATIENT WHO IS SEVERELY
MENTALLY ILL, AND THEY COULD DO
SOMETHING?
I COULD SEE THE SLIPPERY SLOPE
OF WHAT YOU'RE GOING TO BE
ASKING A TRAINED MENTAL
PROFESSIONAL.
>> THAT'S THE WHOLE POINT.
YOU WANT TO GET BEFORE THAT
POINT.
YOU WANT TO SEE THEM BEFORE THEY
ARE POTENTIALLY IMMINENT HARM TO
THEMSELVES OR TO OTHERS.
THAT'S THE THING.
MENTAL ILLNESS IS TREATED ONLY
IN CRISIS SITUATIONS RIGHT NOW.
>> EVERY BUDGET CUT CUTS
MEDICAID, WHICH IS THE NUMBER
ONE HEALTH PROVIDER.
>> EVEN FOR PEOPLE WHO ARE
INSURED AND HAVE GOOD RESOURCES,
THIS IS A WAY OF LIFE FOR THEM.
>> IT IS A TERRIBLE CONUNDRUM.
WE KEEP TALKING ABOUT THAT
INTERSECTION BETWEEN A GUN
CULTURE, A VIOLENT CULTURE,
ACCESS TO WEAPONS, AND LACK OF
FUNDING FOR MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES.
REALLY IT'S A TERRIBLE --
>> IT'S NOT AN EITHER/OR.
YOU'VE GOT TO TALK ABOUT BOTH.
>> THERE ARE MANY PEOPLE IN THIS
COMMUNITY TURNING TO PLACES OF
WORSHIP TO GET A SENSE OF
COMFORT.
WE'RE GOING TO TALK TO A YOUNG
MAN WHO'S A LOCAL RELIGIOUS
LEADER FOR YOUNG PEOPLE, TALKING
ABOUT WHAT THEY'RE DOING TO HELP
THIS SMALL TOWN GRIEVE.
A Hybrid? Most are
just no fun to drive.
Now, here's one that will
make you feel alive.
Meet the five-passenger
Ford C-MAX Hybrid.
C-MAX says ha.
C-MAX says wheeee.
Which is what you get,
don't you see?
Cause C-MAX has lots more
horsepower than Prius v,
a hybrid that C-MAX
also bests in MPG.
Say hi to the all-new 47
combined MPG C-MAX Hybrid.
>>> IT IS IN SUCH TIMES OF
ALMOST UNBEARABLE LOSS THAT WE
SEEK THE COMFORT WITH OUR
CREATOR AND THAT ARTIFICIAL
DIVISIONS OF FAITH FALL AWAY TO
REVEAL A NATION OF MOTHERS AND
FATHERS, BROTHERS AND SISTERS,
SONS AND DAUGHTERS -- ALL UNITED
IN A DESIRE TO BRING HEALING AND
RENEWED HOPE.
>> LAST NIGHT THE CLERGY HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, GATHERED
TO OFFER PRAYERS AND MESS GEAGEF
HOPE TO THE GRIEVING
COMMUNITIES.
YOU JUST SAW THE DIRECTOR OF NEW
HADEA CENTER OF NEWTOWN.
WHAT CAN YOU SAY TO GIVE
CHILDREN COMFORT?
YOU'RE THE YOUTH DIRECTOR.
I KNOW YOU'RE DEALING WITH A LOT
OF CHILDREN.
WHAT CAN YOU POSSIBLY SAY THAT
MAKES SENSE OF SOMETHING LIKE
THIS?
>> IT'S VERY HARD BECAUSE A LOT
OF CHILDREN STILL HAVEN'T REALLY
WRAPPED THEIR HEADS AROUND IT,
AND I DON'T THINK THEY REALLY
WILL UNDERSTAND THE GRAVITY OF
WHAT REALLY HAPPENED.
IT IS VERY DIFFICULT, ESPECIALLY
FOR PEOPLE IN THE SURROUNDING
AREAS.
I KNOW A LOT OF TOWNS, NEARBY
TOWNS WERE AFFECTED AND ON
LOCKDOWN TOO.
A LOT OF PEOPLE STILL TRYING TO
MAKE SENSE OF EVERYTHING.
>> I WAS SPEAKING TO A PARENT OF
SOMEONE WHO DIED IN THE VIRGINIA
TECH MASSACRE.
HE TOLD ME, IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO
MOVE ON, BUT YOU CAN MOVE
FORWARD.
>> YEAH, IT'S TRUE.
IT'S GOING TO BE DIFFICULT TO
RETURN TO THINGS BEING NORMAL.
THERE'S ALWAYS GOING TO BE THAT
KIND OF -- THEY SAY TIME HEALS
ALL WOUNDS, BUT THERE'S STILL
GOING TO BE A SCAR, IF THAT
MAKES SENSE.
THERE'S ALWAYS GOING TO BE A
REMINDER, BUT IT JUST -- YOU
HAVE TO JUST KEEP MOVING ON AND
TAKE MEASURES TO -- YOU LEARN
FROM THE PAST.
IT'S -- WHAT'S THE WORD I'M
LOOKING FOR?
YOU'RE ALWAYS GOING TO BE
REMINDED OF IT.
THERE'S NO WAY TO FORGET.
>> WHEN DO YOU THINK THE FIRST
TIME YOU'LL HAVE A SERMON, A
FIRST WEEKEND WHEN YOU WILL NOT
BE TALKING ABOUT THIS.
WHEN WILL THAT BE?
IS
>> I DON'T KNOW, QUITE HONESTLY.
I THINK IT'S GOING TO BE ON
EVERYBODY'S MINDS FOR A LONG
TIME.
IT'S VERY RAW.
IT'S VERY REAL.
IT STILL FEELS VERY UNREAL TO
PEOPLE, LIKE I'M STILL IN A
STATE OF SHOCK.
I STILL -- IT STILL FEELS WEIRD
TO WAKE UP AND REALIZE THIS
WASN'T JUST A BAD DREAM.
THIS ACTUALLY HAPPENED.
>> YOU'RE A LOCAL.
YOU WENT TO SCHOOL HERE.
YOU GREW UP HERE.
>> I GREW UP IN NEWTOWN.
>> SO DOES IT MAKE IT EASIER FOR
YOU IN SOME WAYS BECAUSE THESE
ARE YOUR PEOPLE THAT YOU'RE
COUNSELING, OR IS IT HARDER
BECAUSE THIS IS YOUR TOWN AND
SOMETHING TERRIBLE HAS HAPPENED
HERE?
>> I THINK, IN A WAY, IT HELPS
BECAUSE YOU KNOW THE PEOPLE, BUT
AT THE SAME TIME, IT'S DIFFICULT
BECAUSE YOU'RE EXPERIENCING THE
SAME THING THEY'RE GOING
THROUGH, AND YOU NEED IT JUST AS
BAD AS THE OTHER PERSON THAT
YOU'RE COUNSELING BECAUSE IT'S A
SHOCK FOR YOU AS WELL.
>> WHAT KINDS OF QUESTIONS ARE
THE YOUNG PEOPLE ASKING YOU?
WHAT'S THE THING THAT THEY WANT
TO KNOW?
>> A LOT OF PEOPLE, A LOT OF
ESPECIALLY THE YOUNG KIDS, LIKE
ESPECIALLY ON FRIDAY AND THIS
WEEKEND, THEY DON'T KNOW.
THEY'RE HEARING ALL THE
INFORMATION FROM THEIR PARENTS.
INFORMATION FROM THE NEWS, AND
EVERYONE HAS DIFFERENT STORIES,
AND A LOT OF KIDS JUST WANT TO
KNOW WHAT HAPPENED OR IF -- OR
WHAT'S -- BASICALLY, WHAT'S
GOING ON BECAUSE SOMETIMES THEY
DON'T WANT TO TELL -- SOME OF
THE CHILDREN ARE VERY YOUNG.
YOU DON'T WANT TO TELL A
5-YEAR-OLD THE GRAVITY OF WHAT
HAPPENED.
AND PEOPLE JUST SAY IT WAS BAD
GUYS, OR THEY'RE GOING TO TELL
THEM ONCE THEY'RE A LITTLE MORE
READY.
>> HOW DO YOU FIND IS THE BEST
WAY TO COMMUNICATE WITH THESE
CHILDREN?
>> I DON'T WANT TO MUDDY IT, BUT
I DON'T WANT TO TELL THEM
SOMETHING THAT WOULD BE, "A,"
TOO SHOCKING OR, "B," DON'T
UNDERSTAND THE GRAVITY OF IT.
YOU HAVE TO TELL THEM VERY --
NOT -- I'M A MIDDLE
GROUND.
>> RIGHT, THERE'S A MIDDLE
YOU CAN'T GIVE THEM THE EXPLICIT
DETAILS.
YOU HAVE TO TELL THEM SOMETHING
VERY BAD HAPPENED.
>> I DON'T KNOW HOW YOU DO YOUR
JOB.
JASON GRAVES, THANK YOU FOR YOUR
TIME.
IT'S A TERRIBLE TASK YOU HAVE
NOW AND FOR THE NEXT SEVERAL
MONTHS AND YEARS MAYBE BECAUSE I
DON'T THINK THIS IS A PROCESS
THAT'S GOING TO BE COMPLETED FOR
ANYONE ANY TIME SOON CERTAINLY.
>> AND AS OUR SPECIAL COVERAGE
HERE CONTINUES FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WE WILL HAVE A CNN
EXCLUSI
EXCLUSIVE.
WE'RE GOING TO HEAR FROM THE
FAMILY OF DAWN HOCHSPRUNG.
SHE, OF COURSE, WAS THE
PRINCIPAL AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
SHE LOST HER LIFE TRYING TO
SUBDUE THE GUNMAN MOMENTS BEFORE
SHE WAS KILLED.
SO WE HAVE ONGOING WEBINARS
AND INTERACTIVE LEARNING,
PLUS, IN-BRANCH SEMINARS
AT OVER 500 LOCATIONS,
WHERE OUR DEDICATED SUPPORT
TEAMS HELP YOU KNOW MORE
SO YOUR MONEY CAN DO MORE.
[ Rodger ] AT SCOTTRADE,
SEVEN DOLLAR TRADES
ARE JUST THE START.
OUR TEAMS HAVE THE
INFORMATION YOU WANT
WHEN YOU NEED IT.
IT'S ANOTHER REASON
MORE INVESTORS ARE SAYING...
[ All ]
I'M WITH SCOTTRADE.
>>> NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
SWALLOWED BY GRIEF THIS MORNING
AFTER THE UNIMAGINABLE LOSS OF
20 CHILDREN AND 6 ADULTS ALL
KILLED INSIDE AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
TODAY THEY PREPARE TO BURY THE
FIRST OF THE VICTIMS.
>> WE WILL MOVE ON.
WE WILL NEVER FORGET.
WE WILL IN MANY WAYS BE MADE
STRONGER.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA VISITING
GREE
GRIEVING FAMILIES AND SHOWING
SUPPORT DURING AN EVENING VIGIL
SAYS WE MUST DO MORE.
>> WE CAN'T TOLERATE THIS
ANYMORE.
THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
NOW QUESTIONS AROUND THE TRAGEDY
AS WE FORGET ABOUT THAT
UNFORGETTABLE FRIDAY MORNING,
BUT THE ULTIMATE QUESTION
REMAINS, WHY DID IT HAPPEN?
>>> WELCOME, EVERYONE.
YOU'RE WATCHING A SPECIAL
EDITION OF "STARTING POINT."
WE'RE COMING TO YOU LIVE THIS
MORNING FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AND I'M JOINED BY
"EARLY START" CO-ANCHOR JOHN
BERMAN.
THERE ARE TWO 6-YEAR-OLD BOYS
WHO WILL BE LAID TO REST THIS
MORNING AS KIDS AROUND THE
COUNTRY WILL BE HEADING FOR
CLASS.
FUNERAL SCHEDULED FOR JACK
PINTO, LITTLE GUY WHO LOVED THE
NEW YORK GIANTS.
AND NOAH POZNER, THE YOUNGEST OF
THE 26 VICTIMS WHO DIED INSIDE
THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
ON FRIDAY.
HE WAS A TWIN.
HIS SISTER SURVIVED.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA WAS IN TOWN
LAST NIGHT, FIRST TRYING TO
COMFORT THE GRIEVING IN PRIVATE,
AND THEN PUBLICLY TRYING TO USE
HIS POWERS AS PRESIDENT TO STOP
THESE UNSPEAKABLE ACTS.
>> THIS IS OUR FIRST TASK,
CARING FOR OUR CHILDREN.
CAN WE TRULY SAY AS A NATION
THAT WE'RE MEETING OUR
OBLIGATIONS.
>> SWING IT AROUND.
OKAY.
>> COME NOW ALMIGHTY KING.
ONE, TWO, THREE, READY AND GO.
♪ COME NOW ALMIGHTY KING
>> WE WILL BE REMEMBERING THE
FALLEN ALL MORNING.
YOU'RE GOING TO GET TO KNOW MORE
ABOUT ALL THE VICTIMS, LIKE ANA
MARQUEZ-GREEN
MARQUEZ-GREEN, THIS ADORABLE
LITTLE GIRL WHO LOVED TO SING
AND WRITE LOVE LETTERS TO HER
PARENTS.
>> IT'S HORRIBLE LOOKING AT
THESE CHILDREN.
>> BEAUTIFUL, BEAUTIFUL LITTLE
GIRL.
WE WANT THE FOCUS TO BE ON THE
VICTIMS AS MUCH AS POSSIBLE, BUT
MORE INFORMATION ON THE
SUSPECTED SHOOTER.
WHAT POLICE SAY ABOUT HOW HE GOT
INTO THE SCHOOL AND WHY HE MAY
HAVE CHOSEN THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AS HIS TARGET.
>> 20 FUNERALS FOR 20 CHILDREN,
THE FIRST OF WHICH BEING HELD IN
NEWTOWN.
SANDRA ENDOOUTSIDE THE CHURCH IN
THE COMMUNITY HAS MORE FOR US.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING,
SOLEDAD.
THE PAIN OF THIS COMMUNITY BEING
FELT ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
LAST NIGHT PRESIDENT OBAMA
SPEAKING TO RESIDENTS HERE AT
NEWTOWN, OFFERING WORDS OF
COMFORT AND SUPPORT AND ALSO
OFFERING CONDOLENCES FROM ACROSS
THE NATION.
>> AS A COMMUNITY, YOU'VE
INSPIRED US, NEWTOWN.
IN THE FACE OF INDESCRIBABLE
VIOLENCE, IN THE FACE OF
UNCONSCIONABLE EVIL, YOU'VE
LOOKED OUT FOR EACH OTHER.
YOU'VE CARED FOR ONE ANOTHER.
AND YOU'VE LOVED ONE ANOTHER.
THIS IS HOW NEWTOWN WILL BE
REMEMBERED, AND WITH TIME AND
GOD'S GRACE, THAT LOVE WILL SEE
YOU THROUGH.
>> THE PRESIDENT ALSO MET WITH
VICTIMS' FAMILY MEMBERS, AND
LAST NIGHT THE DAUGHTER, THE
30-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER OF SLAIN
PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG WROTE
THIS TWEET.
"MY MOM WOULD BE SO PROUD TO SEE
PRESIDENT OBAMA HOLDING HER
GRANDDAUGHTER, BUT NOT AS PROUD
AS I AM OF HER."
AGAIN, TWO FUNERALS TODAY, ONE
FOR 6-YEAR-OLD NOAH POZNER, AND
ANOTHER FOR 6-YEAR-OLD JACK
PINTO.
18 MORE FUNERALS FOR THE
CHILDREN OF FRIDAY'S TRAGEDY IN
THE DAYS TO COME.
AND THE SCHOOLS HERE IN NEWTOWN
WILL BE CLOSED TODAY, AS STAFF
TALK TO EXPERTS TO FIGURE OUT
HOW TO DEAL WITH THIS TRAGEDY
AND HOW TO TALK TO STUDENTS.
THE STUDENTS AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY, THEY WILL REMAIN OUT
OF SCHOOL UNTIL THE NEIGHBORING
SCHOOL COULD ACCOMMODATE THESE
STUDENTS, AND THAT WILL BE
FIGURED OUT IN THE DAYS TO COME.
SOLEDAD?
>> SANDRA ENDOFOR US THIS
MORNING.
THANK YOU, SANDRA.
APPRECIATE IT.
>> THE INVESTIGATION INTO THIS
MASSACRE IS A PAINSTAKING
PROCESS.
IT'S BEING CONDUCTED AROUND THE
CLOCK BY THE STATE POLICE.
POLICE HAVE NOW POSITIVELY
IDENTIFIED ADAM LANZA AS THE
GUNMAN.
THEY ALSO CONFIRMED THAT HE DID,
IN FACT, KILL HIMSELF.
WHAT WE DON'T KNOW YET IS
PRECISELY WHY HE TARGETED THE
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL AND ALL THOSE
20 INNOCENT CHILDREN INSIDE.
>> ALISON KOSIK HAS THE LATEST
ON THE INVESTIGATION FOR US.
SHE'S OUTSIDE THE SUSPECT'S HOME
THIS MORNING WITH MORE.
ALISON, GOOD MORNING.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING,
SOLEDAD.
WE ARE GETTING A CLOSER LOOK AT
WHERE ADAM LANZA LIVED WITH HIS
MOTHER NANCY AT THE HOUSE RIGHT
BEHIND ME.
UP ON THE HILL, IT ALMOST LOOKS
PICTURE PERFECT WITH A WREATH
OVER THE FRONT DOOR THERE.
WE'RE ALSO LEARNING NEW DETAILS
OF HOW THIS GUNMAN GOT INTO THE
SCHOOL, KNOWING THAT YOU HAD TO
BE BUZZED IN AS OF 9:30, THAT
THE DOORS WERE LOCKED AS OF
9:30, THAT HE SHOT HIS WAY INTO
THE SCHOOL.
WE'RE ALSO LEARNING HOW MANY
WEAPONS HE HAD WITH HIM AND HOW
MUCH AMMUNITION HE WAS CARRYING
AS WELL.
THE GUNMAN, ADAM LANZA, FIRED
DOZENS OF BULLETS USING A
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE ON HIS
VICTIMS, LEAVING A PISTOL TO
KILL HIMSELF.
>> THE WEAPON THAT WAS UTILIZED
MOST OF THE TIME DURING THIS
HORRIFIC CRIME WAS IDENTIFIED AS
A BUSHMASTER AR-15 ASSAULT TYPE
WEAPON.
HAD HIGH CAPACITY MAGAZINES,
AND IN ADDITION TO THAT, THE
SUBJECT HAD IN HIS POSSESSION A
GLOCK 10 MILLIMETER, SIG
SAUER .9 MILLIMETER, AND ALL
WEAPONS HAD MULTIPLE MAGAZINES
AND ADDITIONAL AMMUNITION.
>> Reporter: AS AUTHORITIES
CONTINUE TO FOCUS THEIR EFFORT
ON THE SCHOOL CRIME SCENE, WE'RE
LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE
SHOOTER'S ACTIVITIES IN THE
DAYS, WEEKS, AND MONTHS LEADING
UP TO THE SECOND WORST MASS
SHOOTING IN HISTORY.
LANZA VISITED A GUN RANGE.
WE DO NOT KNOW WHERE OR WHEN.
AN ATF SPOKESWOMAN ALSO TELLS
CNN HIS MOTHER, NANCY LANZA,
VISITED A SHOOTING RANGE
MULTIPLE TIMES.
HER SON ALSO KILLED HER.
AS FOR MOTIVE, AUTHORITIES ARE
STILL SEARCHING FOR ANSWERS.
>> WE'RE PLEASED WITH THE WORK
THAT'S BEEN DONE SO FAR.
I'M HOPING THAT HELPS ANSWER
THAT QUESTION.
WE'RE PLEASED WITH THE PROGRESS
THAT WE'RE MAKING.
THIS IS A VERY LONG, TEDIOUS
PROCESS.
>> Reporter: AND FEDERAL AGENTS
CONTINUE CHASING LOTS OF LEADS,
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHAT THIS
GUNMAN WAS UP TO IN THOSE DAYS,
WEEKS, AND MONTHS BEFORE THIS
SHOOTING.
THEY'RE VISITING AS MANY AS 30
GUN RANGES AND HUNDREDS OF GUN
DEALERS IN THE AREA.
SOLEDAD?
>> ALISON KOSIK FOR US.
LIEUTENANT VANCE FROM THE STATE
POLICE DESCRIBED IT, ALISON, AS
PEELING BACK THE LAYERS OF THE
ONION.
WE CAN SEE IN YOUR REPORT
THERE'S STILL A LOT TO DIG INTO,
MAYBE SOME QUESTIONS THEY MAY BE
ABLE TO ANSWER ULTIMATELY.
THANK YOU FOR THAT REPORT.
WANT TO GET TO STEVEN BARTON.
STEVEN WAS HIT BY 25 SHOTGUN
PELLETS IN HIS FACE, HIS NECK,
AND HIS CHEST.
HAPPENED DURING THE AURORA,
COLORADO MOVIE THEATER SHOOTING
BACK IN JULY.
YOU MIGHT REMEMBER THAT 12
PEOPLE WERE KILLED, 58 PEOPLE
WOUNDED ON THAT DAY.
STEVEN CURRENTLY WORKS AS AN
OUTREACH AND POLICY ASSOCIATE
FOR MAYORS AGAINST ILLEGAL GUNS.
HE ALSO LIVES ABOUT TEN MINUTES
FROM HERE.
YOU'VE HAD SO MUCH INTERACTION
WITH GUNS IN A TERRIBLE WAY FROM
SORT OF YOUR HOMETOWN TO WHAT
YOU EXPERIENCED IN AURORA,
COLORADO.
I WANT TO START BY PLAYING A
LITTLE BIT OF WHAT THE PRESIDENT
SAID IN THE VIGIL FROM LAST
NIGHT.
LISTEN.
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS, I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT, TO MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS, TO PARENTS
AND EDUCATORS, IN AN EFFORT
AIMED AT PREVENTING MORE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS.
>> HE SAID LAW ENFORCEMENT,
MENTAL HEALTH PROFESSIONALS,
PARENTS -- ALL OF THEM NEED TO
COME TOGETHER TO DO SOMETHING.
HAVE YOU BEEN DISAPPOINTED IN
WHAT THE PRESIDENT HAS DONE SO
FAR?
>> CERTAINLY.
WE HAVE BASICALLY HEARD THE SAME
MESSAGE AFTER AURORA, AFTER
TUCSON, AND THOSE WORDS WEREN'T
FOLLOWED BY ANY ACTION.
I MEAN, HE SPOKE MORE FORCEFULLY
LAST NIGHT, BUT IT REMAINS TO BE
SEEN IF ANYTHING WILL ACTUALLY
COME OF THOSE WORDS.
>> WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE TO SEE?
IF YOU COULD WRITE LEGISLATION
AND GET IT PASSED TOMORROW, WHAT
WOULD IT INCLUDE?
>> THE EASIEST WAY TO START
REDUCING THE NUMBER OF DEATHS BY
GUNS IN THIS COUNTRY IS BY JUST
REQUIRING A BACKGROUND CHECK FOR
EVERY GUN SALE.
CURRENTLY, 40% OF GUNS SOLD IN
THIS COUNTRY UNDER FEDERAL LAW
AREN'T SUBJECT TO A BACKGROUND
CHECK.
THERE'S BEEN A LOT OF TALK ABOUT
HIGH CAP MAGAZINES, ASSAULT
WEAPONS, BUT IF YOU WANT TO
REDUCE THE 34 AMERICANS MURDERED
WITH GUNS EVERY SINGLE DAY,
BACKGROUND CHECKS ARE THE
EASIEST WAY TO DO THAT AND THE
SIMPLEST WAY TO DO THAT.
>> "THE NEW YORK TIMES" IS
REPORTING THAT, AFTER THE
SHOOTING IN AURORA, THAT WAS
SOMETHING THAT WAS DISCUSSED.
THE JUSTICE DEPARTMENT DID PUT
TOGETHER A LIST OF THINGS THAT
COULD BE DONE.
IT WAS JUST NEVER BROUGHT UP OR
PRESENTED AS SOMETHING TO ENACT.
IS THAT FRUSTRATING TO YOU?
>> DEFINITELY.
ESPECIALLY WHEN YOU CONSIDER
IT'S A MEASURE THAT ENJOYS WIDE
SUPPORT IN THE PUBLIC, EVEN
AMONG NRA GUN OWNERS.
>> IT WOULD NOT HAVE HELPED IN
THIS CASE, THOUGH.
WE KNOW THAT THESE GUNS IN THIS
PARTICULAR CASE, IN THIS
TRAGEDY, WHICH IS WHAT HAS
REALLY, I THINK, KIND OF GRABBED
PEOPLE'S ATTENTION FINALLY, IF
YOU WILL, THAT WOULD NOT HAVE
MADE A DIFFERENCE.
>> AND THAT'S THE UNFORTUNATE
REALITY OF HAVING GUNS IN A FREE
SOCIETY IS THAT WE CAN'T STOP
ALL VIOLENT ACTS.
BUT THERE ARE SOME PRETTY EASY
MEASURES THAT ARE AGREED UPON BY
MANY PEOPLE, SUCH AS HAVING
BACKGROUND CHECKS.
AND THAT, I THINK, IS A STARTING
POINT.
AND THEN BEYOND THAT, WE CAN
HAVE DISCUSSIONS.
THAT TO ME IS THE BEST WAY TO DO
THIS.
>> STEVEN BARTON, THANK YOU FOR
TALKING WITH US THIS MORNING.
WE APPRECIATE IT.
WE SAW A LOT FROM THE MAYORS
AGAINST ILLEGAL GUNS.
THEY'VE REALLY BEEN LEVERAGING
OFF THIS ISSUE TO MAKE THEIR
POSITION KNOWN AND MAYBE GET
SOME TRACTION FOR THEIR ISSUES.
WANT TO GET RIGHT BACK TO
ZORAIDA SAMBOLIN.
SHE'S BEEN COVERING THE DETAILS
OF THE VICTIMS, AS JOHN'S BEEN
MENTIONING ALL MORNING, WE
REALLY WANTED TO FOCUS ON THOSE
WHO LOST THEIR LIVES AND NOT ON
THE NAME OF THE SHOOTER, THE
KILLER.
LET'S GET RIGHT TO ZORAIDA.
>> Reporter: IT'S BEEN REALLY
GREAT TO BE ABLE TO KNOW THESE
KIDS A LITTLE BIT BETTER AND
SOME OF THE ADULTS ALSO WHO LOST
THEIR LIVES.
I WANT TO MENTION WHERE I'M AT.
I'M AT TREADWELL PARK, AND THIS
IS WHERE MOST OF THE PRESS
CONFERENCES ARE TAKING PLACE.
WE KNOW THAT STATE POLICE, WE'RE
EXPECTING TO HEAR FROM THEM
SOMEWHERE AROUND 9:00 OR 9:30
EASTERN.
YOU CAN SEE IT'S LIGHT OUT NOW.
IT'S A SOCCER FIELD.
YOU CAN'T HELP BUT WONDER HOW
MANY OF THESE LITTLE VICTIMS AND
THEIR FAMILIES SPENT TIME
PLAYING IN THIS VERY PARK WHERE
WE ARE NOW.
WE ARE REMEMBERING 7-YEAR-OLD
GRACE McDONNELL.
LITTLE GRACE McDONNELL.
SHE LOVED DRESS UP JEWELRY.
SHE LOVED GYMNASTICS AND SOCCER.
EMILIE PARKER, AGE 6.
HER FATHER SAID SHE COULD LIGHT
UP A ROOM.
SHE WAS A MENTOR TO HER TWO
YOUNGER SISTERS, AGES 3 AND 4.
6-YEAR-OLD JACK PINTO, AN AVID
WRESTLER WITH THE NEWTOWN YOUTH
WRESTLING ASSOCIATION AND A BIG
NEW YORK GIANTS FAN.
HIS FUNERAL IS BEING HELD TODAY.
NOAH POZNER, HE'S ALSO 6 YEARS
OLD.
HIS AUNT SAYS HE HAD A HUGE
HEART AND WAS SO MUCH FUN.
A BIT RAMBUNCTIOUS WITH LOTS OF
SPIRIT.
HE WAS REALLY THE LIGHT OF A
ROOM.
HE WILL ALSO BE LAID TO REST
TODAY.
THEN THERE IS 6-YEAR-OLD
CAROLINE PREVIDI.
HER EFFORTS TO MAKE PEOPLE LAUGH
EARNED HER THE NICKNAME SILLY
CAROLINE.
AND THEN THERE'S 30-YEAR-OLD
LAUREN ROUSSEAU, A SUBSTITUTE
TEACHER AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
HER MOTHER SAID LAUREN WANTED TO
BE A TEACHER BEFORE SHE EVEN
WENT TO KINDERGARTEN.
LATER THIS MORNING, WE'LL BRING
YOU MORE PROFILES OF THE NEWTOWN
SCHOOL SHOOTING VICTIMS.
IT'S SO NICE TO BE ABLE TO GET
TO KNOW THEM A BIT, JOHN AND
SOLEDAD.
>> WE SO APPRECIATE YOU DOING A
NICE REMEMBRANCE OF THE LITTLE
BIT THAT WE KNOW.
SOME OF THESE VICTIMS, 6 AND
7-YEAR-OLDS, IT IS.
IT'S NICE AS WE GET TO HEAR MORE
ABOUT THE CHILDREN AND LESS
ABOUT THE SHOOTER IN THIS CASE.
>> SHE SAID ONE OF THE KIDS
EARNED THE RIPS AND THE TEARS IN
HIS JEANS.
I JUST LOVE THAT IMAGERY.
>> AHEAD THIS MORNING, WE'RE
GOING TO TELL YOU ABOUT A CNN
EXCLUSIVE HONORING DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG.
WE'LL HEAR FROM THE FAMILY OF
THE SANDY HOOK PRINCIPAL.
SHE GAVE HER LIFE WHILE TRYING
TO PROTECT HER STUDENTS.
THAT AHEAD.
>> AND "SATURDAY NIGHT LIVE" DID
AN INCREDIBLE TRIBUTE HONORING
THE LIVES OF THOSE LOST IN THE
NEWTOWN MASSACRE.
I WANT TO LEAVE YOU WITH THE NEW
YORK CITY CHILDREN'S CHORUS.
THEY OPENED THE SHOW WITH SILENT
NIGHT.
"ROUND YON VIRGIN MOTHER AND
CHILD ♪
♪ HOLY INFANT SO TENDER AND
MILD ♪
♪ SLEEP IN HEAVENLY PEACE
SLEEP IN HEAVENLY PEACE ♪
WITH A SELECT TERRAIN DIAL
THAT ADJUSTS THE JEEP
GRAND CHEROKEE'S PERFORMANCE
FOR SPECIFIC WEATHER
AND ROAD CONDITIONS...
♪
...EVEN HEAVY SNOWSTORMS...
WON'T KEEP YOU
FROM GETTING TO WORK.
OUR APOLOGIES.
♪
A BODY AT REST
TENDS TO STAY AT REST...
WHILE A BODY IN MOTION
TENDS TO STAY IN MOTION.
STAYING ACTIVE CAN ACTUALLY
EASE ARTHRITIS SYMPTOMS.
BUT IF YOU HAVE ARTHRITIS,
STAYING ACTIVE
CAN BE DIFFICULT.
PRESCRIPTION CELEBREX
CAN HELP RELIEVE ARTHRITIS PAIN
SO YOUR BODY
CAN STAY IN MOTION.
BECAUSE JUST ONE
200MG CELEBREX A DAY
CAN PROVIDE 24 HOUR RELIEF
FOR MANY WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND INFLAMMATION.
PLUS, IN CLINICAL STUDIES,
CELEBREX IS PROVEN TO IMPROVE
DAILY PHYSICAL FUNCTION
SO MOVING IS EASIER.
CELEBREX CAN BE TAKEN WITH
OR WITHOUT FOOD.
AND IT'S NOT A NARCOTIC.
YOU AND YOUR DOCTOR
SHOULD BALANCE THE BENEFITS
WITH THE RISKS.
ALL PRESCRIPTION NSAIDS,
LIKE CELEBREX, IBUPROFEN,
NAPROXEN, AND MELOXICAM
HAVE THE SAME
CARDIOVASCULAR WARNING.
THEY ALL MAY INCREASE
THE CHANCE
OF HEART ATTACK OR STROKE,
WHICH CAN LEAD TO DEATH.
THIS CHANCE INCREASES
IF YOU HAVE HEART DISEASE
OR RISK FACTORS
SUCH AS HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE
OR WHEN NSAIDS ARE TAKEN
FOR LONG PERIODS.
NSAIDS, INCLUDING CELEBREX,
INCREASE THE CHANCE OF SERIOUS
SKIN OR ALLERGIC REACTIONS
OR STOMACH AND INTESTINE
PROBLEMS,
SUCH AS BLEEDING AND ULCERS,
WHICH CAN OCCUR WITHOUT WARNING
AND MAY CAUSE DEATH.
PATIENTS ALSO TAKING ASPIRIN
AND THE ELDERLY
ARE AT INCREASED RISK FOR
STOMACH BLEEDING AND ULCERS.
DO NOT TAKE CELEBREX IF YOU'VE
HAD AN ASTHMA ATTACK, HIVES,
OR OTHER ALLERGIES TO ASPIRIN,
NSAIDS OR SULFONAMIDES.
GET HELP RIGHT AWAY IF YOU HAVE
SWELLING OF THE FACE OR THROAT,
OR TROUBLE BREATHING.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
YOUR MEDICAL HISTORY
AND FIND AN ARTHRITIS TREATMENT
FOR YOU.
VISIT CELEBREX.COM AND ASK
YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT CELEBREX.
FOR A BODY IN MOTION.
>>> WELCOME BACK.
YOU'RE WATCHING A SPECIAL
EDITION OF "STARTING POINT."
I WANT TO TELL YOU ABOUT THE
PRINCIPAL AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
SHE WAS APPOINTED JUST TWO YEARS
AGO, AND ON FRIDAY, JUST BEFORE
SHE WAS KILLED, DAWN HOCHSPRUNG
TRIED TO SUBDUE THE GUNMAN.
>> CNN'S GARY TUCHMAN SPOKE
EXCLUSIVELY WITH THE FAMILY AS
THEY NOW HONOR HER FAMILY.
>> Reporter: PRINCIPAL DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG WAS QUITE A BIT
YOUNGER THAN HER HUSBAND GEORGE,
BUT WHEN THEY GOT MARRIED, BOTH
FOR THE SECOND TIME, SHE WITH
TWO DAUGHTERS AND HE WITH THREE,
GEORGE WAS MARRYING HIS BOSS.
>> SHE WAS AN ASSISTANT
PRINCIPAL AT OUR SCHOOL.
AT THE MIDDLE SCHOOL, AND I WAS
A SEVENTH GRADE MATH TEACHER AT
THAT TIME.
I JUST FELL IN LOVE WITH HER.
>> Reporter: GEORGE MADE THE BIG
DECISION, THE TIME HAD COME TO
PROPOSE.
>> SHE TURNED ME DOWN FIVE
TIMES.
>> Reporter: YOU ASKED HER TO
MARRY YOU, BUT SHE TURNED YOU
DOWN.
>> FIVE TIMES.
>> Reporter: WHAT HAPPENED THE
SIXTH TIME?
>> THE SIXTH TIME, I WAITED
UNTIL IT WASN'T SUCH ROUGH
SAILING.
>> Reporter: INDEED, GEORGE HAD
BEEN POPPING THE QUESTION ON A
SAILBOAT THEY BOUGHT TOGETHER.
>> WE GOT MARRIED ON A SLOOP OUT
OF MYSTIC.
>> Reporter: BETH, AMY, AND ANN
ARE GEORGE'S DAUGHTERS FROM A
FIRST MARRIAGE.
ERICA IS DAWN'S DAUGHTER FROM A
THEIR DAUGHERTY NAWAZ OUT OF THE
HOUSE.
THEY'RE A BLENDED BUT CLOSE
FAMILY WITH 11 GRANDCHILDREN.
>> WE BUILT A BEAUTIFUL HOUSE IN
THE ADIRONDACKS, OUR DREAM.
THE DREAM WAS A CHRONOLOGICAL
DREAM.
IT WAS GOING TO BE DAWN'S HOUSE
BECAUSE I WAS GOING TO DIE.
I'M MUCH OLDER THAN DAWN.
IT WAS GOING TO BE DAWN'S HOUSE.
DAWN'S GRANDCHILDREN AND ALL
THESE CHILDREN COULD USE THE
HOUSE ON THE LAKE, AND IT WOULD
BE WONDERFUL.
WE BUILT ROOMS DOWNSTAIRS FOR
KIDS.
IT WAS GOING TO BE DAWN'S HOUSE
ULTIMATELY.
WITH ALL THE CHILDREN.
ALL THE CHILDREN.
AND NOW IT'S ME.
I CAN'T -- I DON'T THINK I CAN
DO THAT.
>> Reporter: BUT I WANT TO
REITERATE TO YOU, GEORGE, YOU
HAVE THESE BEAUTIFUL DAUGHTERS
AND SON-IN-LAWS AND
GRANDCHILDREN, AND EVERYONE WILL
BE HERE TO TAKE CARE OF YOU.
IS THAT RIGHT, LADIES?
>> YES.
>> MY JOB HAS ALWAYS BEEN TO
TAKE CARE OF OTHER PEOPLE.
>> Reporter: IT'S ALL RIGHT IF
SOMEONE TAKES CARE OF YOU FOR A
WHILE.
>> NO ONE HAS EVER TAKEN CARE OF
ME.
>> STOP BEING SO STUBBORN.
>> Reporter: WHILE DAWN WAS THE
PRINCIPAL AT SANDY HOOK, GEORGE
WAS STILL AT THE MIDDLE SCHOOL
WHERE THEY MET.
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE DAY ON
FRIDAY, THIS IS HOW GEORGE FOUND
OUT WHAT HAPPENED.
>> THE KIDS CAME UP WITH A
COMPUTER AND SAID SOMETHING IS
HAPPENING AT SANDY HOOK SCHOOL,
AND YOUR WIFE'S BEEN KILLED.
>> Reporter: GEORGE RACED OUT OF
SCHOOL AND INTO A NIGHTMARE.
LIKE ALL THE FAMILIES OF
VICTIMS, THEY WANT TO KNOW MORE.
ON THIS DAY, THEY HAVE LEARNED
MORE.
TWO TEACHERS WHO SURVIVED TOLD
GEORGE THEY WERE HAVING A
MEETING WITH DAWN WHEN THE SHOTS
STARTED RINGING OUT.
>> DAWN PUT HERSELF IN JEOPARDY,
AND I HAVE BEEN ANGRY ABOUT
THAT, ANGRY UNTIL JUST NOW
TODAY, WHEN I MET THE TWO WOMEN
THAT SHE TOLD TO GO UNDER
SHELTER WHILE SHE ACTUALLY
CONFRONTED THE GUNMAN.
SHE COULD NOT -- SHE COULD HAVE
AVOIDED THAT, AND SHE DIDN'T.
I KNEW SHE WOULDN'T.
SO I'M NOT ANGRY ANYMORE.
I'M NOT ANGRY.
I'M NOT ANGRY AT HER.
I'M JUST VERY SAD.
AND THEY SAID, WE'RE AT THE
MEETING.
THERE WERE GUNSHOTS.
SOMEBODY SHOT THE WINDOW.
SOMEBODY CAME IN, INTO THE --
NOT INTO THE OFFICE, BUT INTO
THE BUILDING, THE FOYER OF THE
BUILDING, AND DAWN TOLD US TO GO
HIDE.
AND SHE AND AT LEAST ONE OTHER
TEACHER RAN OUT AND ACTUALLY
TRIED TO SUBDUE THE KILLER.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE THAT COMES
FROM.
DAWN WAS, WHAT, 5'2".
>> Reporter: EVERYONE HERE IS SO
PROUD, NO ONE MORE SO THAN
ERICA, WHO SAID HER MOM WAS
ALWAYS THERE FOR HER DAUGHTERS.
>> EVERY GAME, SHE WAS THERE.
EVERY PRACTICE, SHE WAS THERE.
ALL OF MY SISTER'S CHEERLEADING
STUFF, SHE WAS THERE.
EVERY DANCE COMPETITION.
SHE WAS DOING HOMEWORK ON THE
BLEACHERS, BUT SHE WAS THERE.
AND SHE WAS MY ROCK.
MY ROCK.
>> Reporter: AND NOW SHE IS A
HERO TOO.
FINAL THING I WANT TO ASK YOU IS
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY TO YOUR MOM
RIGHT NOW?
>> COME BACK.
JUST COME BACK.
>> Reporter: THEY ARE SUCH A
KIND, WONDERFUL FAMILY.
WE'RE SO GRATEFUL THEY ALLOWED
US INTO THEIR HOME TO SPEND THE
TIME WITH THEM.
OF THE FIVE DAUGHTERS, TWO OF
THEM LIVE HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
THREE OF THEM, ONE OF THEM LIVES
IN PENNSYLVANIA, ONE IN NEW
HAMPSHIRE, ONE IN LONDON, BUT
THEY ALL STAYED TOGETHER WITH
THEIR FATHER FOR THE TIME BEING,
STRENGTH IN NUMBERS.
YOU KNOW WHAT'S REALLY AMAZING
TO ME, IT'S ALMOST 18 YEARS AGO
WE HAD THE OKLAHOMA CITY MANY
BOOING.
19 CHILDREN WERE KILLED IN THE
OKLAHOMA CITY MANY BOOINBOMBING
OF 168 PEOPLE.
BILL CLINTON CAME.
THERE WAS A SERVICE LIKE LAST
NIGHT.
IT WAS SUCH TRAUMATIC DEJA VU
FOR ME EXPERIENCING THAT AND
SEEING THE SAME THING OVER
AGAIN.
IT'S SO DEPRESSING.
>> YOU COULD SEE THE LOVE IN
THAT FAMILY, BUT ALSO THE
ADMIRATION THAT THEY HAD FOR
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG.
>> THEY LOVED HER.
THEY WERE SO PROUD OF HER, AND
THEY JUST WANTED THAT STORY TO
GET OUT.
I HOPE WE DID IT JUSTICE.
>> YOU DID IT GREAT JUSTICE,
GARY.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>>> AHEAD THIS MORNING, HE SPOKE
WITH ONE OF THE PARENTS OF THE
COLUMBINE SHOOTERS.
WHY DO SOME MEN BECOME MASS
MURDERERS?
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE THE SPECIAL
COVERAGE LIVE FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT IN A MOMENT.
[ NyQuil Bottle ] HEY TYLENOL,
YOU KNOW WE'RE KINDA LIKE TWINS.
[ Tylenol Bottle ] WE ARE?
YEAH WE BOTH RELIEVE COUGHS,
SNEEZING,
ACHES, FEVERS.
AND I RELIEVE
NASAL CONGESTION.
OVERACHIEVER.
[ Female Announcer ] TYLENOL®
COLD MULTI-SYMPTOM NIGHTTIME
RELIEVES NASAL CONGESTION.
NYQUIL® COLD AND FLU DOESN'T.
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
(Announcer) When Subaru owners
look in the mirror,
they see more than themselves.
So we celebrate our year-end
with the "share the love" event.
Get a great deal on a new Subaru
and 250 dollars goes to your
choice of five charities.
By the end of this, our fifth
year,
our total can reach almost 25
million dollars.
It's a nice reflection on us
all.
Now through January 2nd.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO "STARTING
POINT," AS WE ARE TRACKING THE
LATEST STORIES.
>>> NEW WORD FROM BRISTOL,
CONNECTICUT, ONLY 30 MILES FROM
THE SCENE OF THE NEWTOWN
MASSACRE, POLICE ARRESTED A
STUDENT FOR ALLEGEDLY MAKING A
THREAT AGAINST BRISTOL CENTRAL
HIGH SCHOOL.
AUTHORITIES NOT REVEALING THE
NATURE OF THE THREAT, BUT THEY
SAID THAT NO ONE WAS IN ANY
DANGER.
>>> SOUTH CAROLINA GOVERNOR
NICKI HALEY WILL ANNOUNCE IN A
FEW HOURS WHO SHE WILL APPOINT
TO REPLACE RETIRED SENATOR JIM
DEMINT.
DEMINT IS LEAVING THE SENATE
NEXT MONTH TO HEAD UP A
CONSERVATIVE THINK TANK.
>>> PROGRESS IN FISCAL CLIFF
NEGOTIATIONS.
YESTERDAY A SOURCE FAMILIAR WITH
THE TALKS TOLD CNN THAT HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER HAS OFFERED
TO EXTEND THE DEBT LIMIT FOR A
YEAR AS PART OF THE DEFICIT
REDUCTION DEAL.
THE DEBT CEILING, THE AMOUNT THE
GOVERNMENT CAN BORROW, STANDS AT
$16.4 TRILLION.
RAISING IT REQUIRES AN ACT OF
CONGRESS, WHICH REPUBLICANS
STRONGLY OPPOSE.
THAT NEWS CAME ONE DAY AFTER A
SOURCE SAID BOEHNER HAD OFFERED
TO RAISE TAX RATES ON THOSE
AMERICANS WITH ANNUAL INCOMES
OVER $1 MILLION.
>>> U.S. STOCK FUTURES SLIGHTLY
HIGHER THIS MORNING.
CAN LAWMAKERS STRIKE A DEAL TO
AVOID THE $7 TRILLION IN TAX
INCREASES AND SPENDING CUTS OVER
THE NEXT DECADE?
GOING OVER THE CLIFF IS
SOMETHING ECONOMISTS, INCLUDING
FEDERAL RESERVE CHIEF BEN
BERNANKE SAY COULD PULL THE
ECONOMY BACK INTO RECESSION.
MARKETS ARE BEHAVING AS IF WE
WON'T GO OVER THE CLIFF.
THE S&P 500 IS UP ALMOST 12.5%
THIS YEAR.
HISTORICALLY, DECEMBER HAS BEEN
THE STRONGEST MONTH FOR STOCKS
SINCE 1950.
MARKETS USUALLY EXPERIENCE
WHAT'S KNOWN AS A SANTA CLAUS
RALLY.
HOWEVER, THIS YEAR, OF COURSE,
MARKETS HINGE ON THOSE FISCAL
CLIFF NEGOTIATIONS IN
WASHINGTON.
SOLED DAD, JOHN?
>> CHRISTINE, THANKS.
AHEAD ON THIS SPECIAL EDITION OF
"STARTING POINT" COMING TO YOU
FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WHAT
CAUSES A YOUNG MAN TO BECOME SO
VIOLENT AND KILL INNOCENT
PEOPLE?
A PSYCHOLOGY PROFESSOR WHO
STUDIED MASS SHOOTINGS
INTERVIEWED THE FAMILY OF ONE OF
THE COLUMBINE KILLERS.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT WHAT HE
DISCOVERED.
>>> AND SHE DIED TRYING TO SAVE
HER ROOM FULL OF FIRST GRADERS.
VICKI SOTO'S FAMILY TALKS ABOUT
THIS HEROIC YOUNG WOMAN WHEN WE
RETURN.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA THINS
PACK THE BIG TASTE
OF GRANOLA AND DARK CHOCOLATE
INTO ONE PERFECT SQUARE,
UNDER 100 CALORIES.
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA THINS.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY,
YOU'RE WATCHING A SPECIAL
EDITION OF "STARTING POINT," AND
WE'RE COMING TO YOU LIVE FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
TWO LITTLE BOYS, JUST 6 YEARS
OLD, THEY'LL BE BURIED TODAY.
THEY'RE THE FIRST OF THE MORE
THAN TWO DOZEN FUNERALS THAT
FOLKS IN THIS TOWN WILL HAVE TO
ENDURE AFTER FRIDAY'S MASSACRE
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE PLAN FOR ALL THE SURVIVING
STUDENTS IS TO RETURN THEM TO
CLASS AS SOON AS POSSIBLE, BUT
THEY WON'T BE GOING BACK TO
SANDY HOOK, WHICH IS AT THIS
MOMENT A CRIME SCENE SCHOOL.
THEY'RE GOING TO USE THE SCHOOL
IN MONROE, CONNECTICUT, WHICH IS
ROUGHLY SEVEN MILES AWAY FROM
NEWTOWN.
>> YOUNG PEOPLE NATIONWIDE ARE
PAYING THEIR RESPECTS THIS
MORNING WITH A TWITTER CAMPAIGN
URGING EVERYONE TO WEAR GREEN
AND WHITE TODAY.
GREEN AND WHITE, SANDY HOOK'S
SCHOOL COLORS.
>>> LAST NIGHT PRESIDENT OBAMA
WAS HERE.
IN PRIVATE HE CONSOLED GRIEF
STRICKEN PARENTS.
AND PUBLICLY HE OFFERED THIS
MESSAGE OF CONSOLATION.
>> I COME TO OFFER THE LOVE AND
PRAYERS OF A NATION.
>>> OUR PRIMARY FOCUS, OF
COURSE, IS ON THE VICTIMS TODAY,
BUT WE ARE LEARNING MORE ABOUT
THE GUNMAN THIS MORNING.
A RELATIVE SAYS THAT HE WAS
PULLED OUT OF SCHOOL, OUT OF THE
NEWTOWN SCHOOL SYSTEM BY HIS
MOTHER, WHO WAS SOMEHOW UNHAPPY
WITH THEIR PLANS FOR HER
TROUBLED SON.
AND SHE DECIDED TO HOME SCHOOL
HIM INSTEAD, SOME YEARS AGO
OBVIOUSLY.
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, MOURNS THE
LOSS OF 27 OF THEIR OWN.
THE INVESTIGATION INTO THE
SHOOTER AND WHAT DROVE HIM TO
COMMIT SUCH UNSPEAKABLE ACTS.
IT DOES CONTINUE.
>> GAMES GARABIONO IS A
PSYCHOLOGY PROFESSOR AT LOYOLA
LAW SCHOOL AND ALSO THE AUTHOR
OF "LOST BOYS," HOW OUR SONS
TURN VIOLENT AND HOW YOU CAN
SAVE THEM.
YOU LOOK BACK AT WHO DOES THESE
KINDS OF MASS MURDERS, USUALLY
THEY'RE YOUNG, THEY'RE MEN,
THEY'RE SUBURBAN.
WHAT ELSE CAN YOU TELL US THAT'S
A THREAD AMONG THOSE WHO
PERPETRATE THESE CRIMES?
>> AFTER THE FACT, IT SEEMS MUCH
CLEARER THAN BEFORE IT ACTUALLY
HAPPENED.
THESE YOUNG MEN, THESE BOYS ARE
BUILDING A TOWER OF BLOCKS.
EACH BLOCK CONTRIBUTES TO THEM
GETTING TO THIS POINT.
IT'S NOT THE RESULT OF ANY ONE
BLOCK, BUT USUALLY
TEMPERAMENTALLY THEY'RE
PARTICULARLY SENSITIVE, A LITTLE
BIT ODD.
THEY EXPERIENCE SOCIAL
REJECTION.
THEY EXPERIENCE ISOLATION.
BUT ALSO THEY PREPARE FOR THIS.
THEY PLAY VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES
THAT GET THEM READY
PSYCHOLOGICALLY, EVEN
TECHNICALLY.
THEN THEY GET FIXATED ON THIS
DELUSION, THIS IDEA, THAT
SOMEHOW THIS GRANDIOSE ACT OF
VIOLENCE WILL MAKE THEIR LIVES
RESOLVED, THAT IT WILL DEAL WITH
THEIR PROFOUND SADNESS, IT WILL
GIVE BACK TO THE WORLD SOMETHING
THAT THEY FEEL HAS BEEN DONE TO
THEM.
IT DOESN'T MAKE SENSE FROM THE
OUTSIDE, BUT INSIDE, ALL OF THE
KILLERS, INSIDE THIS MAKES SENSE
TO THEM.
WHEN THEY ACTUALLY COMMIT THE
ACT, THEY MAY COME TO THEIR
SENSES AND BECOME LUCID, WHICH
IS ONE REASON WHY THEY OFTEN
KILL THEMSELVES.
>> CAN WE TALK ABOUT THE VIDEO
GAMES?
YOU BROUGHT THIS UP BECAUSE IN
THESE DISCUSSIONS WE INVARIABLY
GET TO THIS NOTION OF VIOLENT
VIDEO GAMES.
IN YOUR RESEARCH, IN YOUR TALKS
WITH THESE KIDS, WHAT KIND OF
ROLE HAVE YOU SEEN THAT THEY
PLAY?
>> THEY PRETTY CLEARLY BREAK
DOWN IMPEDIMENTS TO KILLING.
MOST PEOPLE HAVE A SORT OF
BARRIER, BUT THE VIDEO GAME, AND
MILITARY PSYCHOLOGISTS HAVE
FOUND THIS, WHEN YOU HAVE THE
POINT AND SHOOT VIDEO GAME, IT
BREAKS DOWN THAT INHIBITION
AGAINST KILLING AND PROVIDES A
PRACTICE.
AND I THINK FOR SOME OF THESE
KIDS, IT'S ALMOST AS IF THEY'RE
LIVING OUT THESE VIOLENT VIDEO
GAMES WHEN THEY COMMIT THE ACT.
OF COURSE, THAT BY ITSELF IS NOT
SUFFICIENT TO PRODUCE THIS.
MANY OF THESE OTHER THINGS HAVE
TO BE PRESENT, INCLUDE ACCESS TO
REAL WEAPONS.
NO SOCIETY THAT MAKES
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLES AVAILABLE
SHOULD BE SURPRISED WHEN PEOPLE
ACT OUT THESE DELUSIONAL
SCENARIOS IN THIS VIOLENT WAY
BECAUSE MOST OF THE VIDEO GAMES,
THAT'S EXACTLY THE KIND OF
WEAPON THEY PRACTICE ON.
>> THE FAMILY OF DYLAN KLEBOLD
FROM COLUMBINE GRANTED YOU THE
ONLY INTERVIEW.
I'M CURIOUS TO KNOW IF WHAT THEY
TOLD YOU PROVIDES ANY INSIGHT
INTO WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
GRANTED, WE DON'T KNOW A LOT
ABOUT THE SHOOTER.
WE KNOW ALMOST LESS, IF YOU
WILL, ABOUT HIS MOTHER, WHO HE
WAS LIVING WITH, AND WHO ALSO
WAS A VICTIM AND A GUN
COLLECTOR.
DO YOU SEE ANY KIND OF THREAD OR
INFORMATION FROM THE OTHER CASE
IN COLUMBINE THAT WOULD PROVIDE
SOME INSIGHT IN THIS CASE?
>> WELL, IT'S HARD TO SAY MUCH
TO RESPECT THEIR PRIVACY AND
CONFIDENTIALITY, BUT I HAVE
SPOKEN WITH OTHER KIDS WHO
DIDN'T COMMIT THIS BUT ON THE
VERGE OF DOING IT.
A BOY WHO BROUGHT GUNS AND BOMBS
TO SCHOOL INTENT UPON ONE OF
THESE KINDS OF ACTIONS, AND I
THINK THAT, IF THERE IS A COMMON
THREAD, IT'S THAT THE PARENTS
ARE NOT NECESSARILY OBLIVIOUS TO
WHAT'S GOING ON, BUT THEY DON'T
QUITE UNDERSTAND THE FULL
DIMENSIONS OF IT.
THESE ARE CHILDREN OFTEN WHO
HAVE BEEN A LITTLE ODD OR A
LITTLE UNUSUAL SINCE THEY WERE
VERY YOUNG, AND PARENTS LOVE
THEM.
OF COURSE, THESE ARE PARENTS WHO
TYPICALLY HAVE THE RESOURCES TO
SORT OF KEEP THEIR CHILDREN
AFLOAT THROUGH CHILDHOOD AND
INTO ADOLESCENCE.
A BOY LIKE THIS WHO GREW UP IN
AN INNER CITY, POOR NEIGHBORHOOD
WOULD PROBABLY SORT OF BREAK
DOWN BY THE TIME HE WAS IN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
BUT THESE KIDS ARE KEPT AFLOAT,
AND IT GIVES THEM AN OPPORTUNITY
AS TEENAGERS TO DEVELOP THESE
DELUSIONAL IDEAS TO GET FIXATED
ON THEM, TO PRACTICE WITH THE
VIDEO GAMES, AND THEN TO FIND
ACCESS TO THESE WEAPONS.
SO THE COMMON ELEMENT IS THAT
THEY'RE ACTING OUT AN AMERICAN
SCENARIO THAT IS PROMOTED TO
THEM THROUGH THE MOVIES, THROUGH
VIDEO GAMES, THROUGH THE
CULTURE.
I SPOKE WITH ONE BOY WHO HAD
STUDIED THE COLUMBINE MASSACRE
AS A SORT OF PRIMER ON HOW TO GO
ABOUT DOING THIS.
>> I'M REALLY CURIOUS ABOUT
SOMETHING YOU SAID THERE.
YOU SAID YOU TALKED TO BOYS WHO
WERE ON THE VERGE OF DOING THIS
CRIME.
HOW DO YOU GET THEM NOT TO GO TO
THAT AWFUL PLACE?
>> ONE OF THESE BOYS ACTUALLY
WENT TO SCHOOL, AND A COUPLE OF
TEENAGE GIRLS NOTICED HE SEEMED
A LITTLE OFF THAT DAY.
THEY CALLED THE CAMPUS POLICE
OFFICER.
HE INTERVENED.
WHAT THE BOY SAID WAS HE DIDN'T
WANT TO KILL THESE GIRLS.
SO HE SURRENDERED RATHER THAN GO
FORWARD.
HE ALSO SAID SOMETHING VERY
INTERESTING, WHICH WAS HE DIDN'T
HAVE THE SOCIAL SUPPORT OF
SOMEBODY ELSE SORT OF PUSHING
HIM FORWARD IN THIS, WHICH, OF
COURSE, THE BOYS IN COLUMBINE
HAD.
THEY HAD EACH OTHER.
HE EVEN SAID THAT.
HE SAID, THEY HAD EACH OTHER.
AND HE DIDN'T HAVE ENOUGH TO GO
FORWARD.
NOW, THIS BOY WHO DID THIS, THIS
TERRIBLE THING IN CONNECTICUT,
WE DON'T KNOW, WE MAY NEVER
KNOW.
THE FACT THAT HE KILLED HIS
MOTHER SUGGESTS THAT HE HAD SOME
SORT OF RAGE THAT WAS PART OF
THIS FIXATION AND THAT HIS
MOTHER WAS SOMEHOW TIED UP IN
THIS IDEA THAT HE HAD, THAT HE
HAD TO PAY BACK AGAINST THE
WORLD IN A WAY THAT, IF HE WERE
ALIVE TODAY, EVEN HE MIGHT SEE
HOW CRAZY THAT SEEMS.
>> JAMES GARABINO, THANKS SO
MUCH FOR THE INSIGHT ON THIS.
I FIND THE COMMONALITY THREAD
AND THE WORK YOU'VE DONE REALLY,
REALLY FASCINATING AND
TERRIFYING AT THE SAME TIME.
I WANT TO GET RIGHT BACK TO
ZORAIDA SAMBOLIN.
SHE'S BEEN LOOKING MORE AT THE
VICTIMS IN THIS CASE, TO GIVE US
INSIGHT INTO THEIR LIVES, THEIR
SHORT LIVES IN SOME CASES.
ZORAIDA?
>> Reporter: I'M ACTUALLY AT
TREADWELL PARK.
THIS IS WHERE MOST OF THE PRESS
CONFERENCES TAKE PLACE, AND
WE'RE EXPECTING ONE BY STATE
POLICE SOMEWHERE AROUND 9:00 OR
9:30 EASTERN, AND WE'RE
MONITORING THAT.
OF COURSE, WE'RE GOING TO HAVE
IT FOR YOU.
YES, SOLEDAD, WE ARE REMEMBERING
THE VICTIMS.
WE'LL START HERE REMEMBERING
JESSICA REKOS THIS MORNING.
THE 6-YEAR-OLD LOVED EVERYTHING
ABOUT HORSES AND ASKED SANTA FOR
NEW COWGIRL BOOTS AND A COWGIRL
HAT.
HER FAMILY PROMISED SHE COULD
GET HER OWN HORSE WHEN SHE
TURNED 10 YARDS OLD.
AVIELLE RICHMAN, AGE 6.
THIS LITTLE GIRL LOVED TO READ.
HER FAVORITE BOOKS WERE THE
HARRY POTTER SERIES, AND HER
FAVORITE COLOR WAS RED.
HER SUMMERTIME HOBBY WAS ARCHERY
BECAUSE OF THE MOVIE "BRAVE."
LITTLE BENJAMIN WHEELER, ALSO 6
YEARS OLD.
HIS RABBI SAID, "THERE'S ALWAYS
SOME BRAVE INDIVIDUAL WHO GOES
UP TO THE DANCE FLOOR TO GET
EVERYBODY INVOLVED.
THAT WAS BEN WHEELER."
6-YEAR-OLD ALLISON WYATT.
SHE'S DESCRIBED AS A QUIET, SHY,
AND LOVING LITTLE GIRL.
ALLISON LOVED TO GARDEN WITH HER
MOM AND WAS ALWAYS OUTSIDE IN
THE SUMMER.
RACHEL DAVINO, 29 YEARS OLD, ONE
OF THE SIX ADULTS, ALL WOMEN,
KILLED BY THE SHOOTER AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY.
SHE LOVED KARATE, COOKING,
ANIMALS, PHOTOGRAPHY, AND HER
TWO YOUNGER SIBLINGS.
56-YEAR-OLD MARY SHERLACH, THE
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST.
SHE LIVED IN TRUMBULL,
CONNECTICUT, WITH HER HUSBAND.
SHE ENJOYED GARDENING, READING,
AND GOING TO THE THEATER.
THEN THERE'S 27-YEAR-OLD FIRST
GRADE TEACHER VICTORIA SOTO.
THE OLDEST OF FOUR CHILDREN, SHE
LOVED HER DOG ROXIE.
SHE ALSO WROTE SHE LOVED
FLAMINGOS AND THE NEW YORK
YANKEES.
SOTO SPENT HER FINAL MOMENTS
SHIELDING HER STUDENTS FROM
HARM, HIDING THEM IN A CLOSET
BEFORE THE GUNMAN ENTERED HER
CLASSROOM.
AND HER MOTHER SAYS THAT DOES
NOT SURPRISE HER ONE BIT.
>> SHE WAS TRULY SELFLESS.
SHE WOULD NOT HESITATE TO THINK
TO SAVE ANYONE ELSE BEFORE
HERSELF AND ESPECIALLY CHILDREN.
SHE LOVED THEM MORE THAN LIFE,
AND SHE WOULD DEFINITELY PUT
HERSELF IN FRONT OF THEM ANY
DAY, ANY DAY AND FOR ANY REASON.
IT DOESN'T SURPRISE ANYBODY THAT
KNOWS VICKI THAT SHE DID THIS.
>> Reporter: SOTO'S MOTHER SAYS
THAT TEACHING IS ALL VICKI EVER
WANTED TO DO.
EVER SINCE SHE WAS 3 YEARS OLD,
SHE KNEW THAT WAS HER CALLING.
TO FIND OUT HOW YOU CAN HELP
THOSE AFFECTED BY THE TRAGEDY,
GO TO CNN.COM/IMPACT.
A LOT OF OPTIONS FOR YOU ON HOW
YOU CAN HELP THESE GRIEVING
FAMILIES.
SOLEDAD AND JOHN, I KNOW THE TWO
OF YOU CAN RELATE TO THIS WHOLE
CONCEPT AS PARENTS.
WE KNOW WE WOULD TAKE A BULLET
FOR THESE KIDS, BUT ALL OF THESE
EDUCATORS IN THAT SCHOOL THAT
DAY TREATED THESE CHILDREN LIKE
THEY WERE THEIR OWN.
IT'S SOMETHING YOU WOULD NEVER
EXPECT.
YOU CERTAINLY WOULD WANT TO KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED FOR YOUR CHILD,
BUT IT JUST BREAKS YOUR HEART.
>> IT HAS BEEN AMAZING, I THINK,
THE DEGREE TO WHICH TEACHERS
WERE HEROES IN THIS AND ALSO THE
LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS.
WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT THE SCENE
THAT THEY HAD TO WORK IN AND
DEAL WITH AND HOW THEY WERE
TELLING THOSE CHILDREN AS THEY
WERE LEADING THEM OUT, CLOSE
YOUR EYES SO YOU WON'T SEE
ANYTHING AROUND YOU.
THAT'S JUST HORRIFIC.
THAT'S HORRIFIC.
THANK YOU, ZORAIDA.
WE APPRECIATE THAT.
>>> STILL AHEAD THIS MORNING ON
"STARTING POINT," WE'RE GOING TO
GO BACK TO DEEPAK CHOPRA AND
TALK ABOUT WHAT IT TAKES TO GET
THROUGH A TRAGEDY LIKE THIS AND
FIND ANY INNER PEACE.
WHETHER IT'S FOR AN INDIVIDUAL
OR A COMMUNITY.
HE'LL BE WITH US IN JUST A BIT.
>>> IS IT TIME FINALLY TO
TIGHTEN OUR GUN LAWS?
WE'RE GOING TO TALK TO THE
DIRECTOR OF MAYORS AGAINST
ILLEGAL GUNS.
QUESTIONS?
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
WE'RE BACK THIS MORNING WITH
DEEPAK CHOPRA.
WE'RE LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
I KNOW THAT MANY OF THE THINGS
WE'VE DISCUSSED OVER THE PAST
YEARS HAS BEEN ABOUT FINDING AN
INNER PEACE, AND I WONDER HOW
PEOPLE HERE WILL EVER BE ABLE TO
DO THAT.
>> IN THE TIME LIKE THIS, IN THE
MIDST OF CRISIS, WE WILL
NATURALLY TEND TO COME TOGETHER
TO SUPPORT EACH OTHER, TO LISTEN
TO EACH OTHER, TO PRAY WITH EACH
OTHER, TO GRIEVE.
THEY GO THROUGH A CYCLE OF
DENIAL, ANGER, AND THEN
ULTIMATELY THEY DO RECOVER.
THAT'S THE INTERESTING THING.
IN TWO YEARS MOST PEOPLE WILL
HAVE RECOVERED.
>> WHEN YOU SAY RECOVER, WHAT DO
YOU MEAN BY THAT?
>> THEY MOVE ON TO A NORMAL OR
RELATIVELY NORMAL LIFE.
SOME WILL NEVER RECOVER.
SOME WILL GET POST-TRAUMATIC
STRESS DISORDER AND WILL NEED
ACTUALLY VERY SPECIFIC
TREATMENTS FOR THAT.
THE BIGGER QUESTION IS ARE WE
GOING TO BE DOING THIS SHOW
AGAIN IN THREE MONTHS?
UNLESS WE TAKE ACTION.
>> ANOTHER TRAGEDY.
>> SO MUCH OF WHAT YOU TALK
ABOUT -- I'M FASCINATED BY YOUR
WRITING AND WHAT WE TALK ABOUT,
IS HOW TO BE PRESENT.
TO NOT GET WORKED UP ABOUT THE
PAST OR THE FUTURE.
HOW CAN YOU BE PRESENT IN A
SITUATION LIKE THIS WHEN THE
IMMEDIATE PAST IS SO HORRIFYING?
>> YOU CAN'T FOR THE MOST PART,
BUT YOU SHOULD TRY TO BECAUSE,
IF YOU DO, YOU WILL LOOK FOR
CREATIVE SOLUTIONS.
OTHERWISE, YOU'LL GET CAUGHT UP
IN THE EMOTIONAL DRAMA OF IT,
WHICH IS ALSO VERY MUCH NEEDED
ALSO.
UNLESS YOU HAVE THAT ANGER RIGHT
NOW, UNLESS YOU HAVE THE RAGE
RIGHT NOW, WE MIGHT MISS THE
OPPORTUNITY TO DO SOMETHING
ABOUT IT.
IN FACT, YOU MENTIONED A
CAMPAIGN ON TWITTER FOR PEOPLE
TO WEAR GREEN AND WHITE.
WHY NOT A TWITTER CAMPAIGN FOR
ALL OF THOSE WATCHING US TO LOOK
AT GUN CONTROL AGAIN.
IF THE COLLECTIVE VOICE OF THE
PEOPLE SPEAKS RIGHT NOW IN THE
MIDST OF THIS CRISIS, SOMETHING
WILL HAPPEN.
>> I THINK FOR A LOT OF PEOPLE
WHO ARE WATCHING, NOT HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WHAT DO
THEY DO?
DO YOU GIVE MONEY?
IT'S A RELATIVELY AFFLUENT
COMMUNITY.
>> YOU HUDDLE TOGETHER.
YOU MAKE PEOPLE FEEL SAFE.
>> SO YOU SEND MESSAGES?
>> YOU SEND MESSAGES.
YOU CONGREGATE TOGETHER.
YOU GO TO CHURCH TOGETHER.
YOU PRAY TOGETHER.
AND YOU HELP EACH OTHER.
THIS MOMENT, THERE'S NOTHING
MORE THAN THE COMING TOGETHER OF
PEOPLE AND ACTUALLY ALSO GETTING
IN TOUCH WITH THEIR GRIEF
BECAUSE, IF YOU DON'T WANT TO
GET IN TOUCH WITH THEIR GRIEF,
IT'S ONLY GOING TO FESTER THERE
INTO SOME KIND OF ILLNESS.
>> DO YOU FIND THAT PEOPLE
RECOVER FASTER WHEN THEY GET
INVOLVED IN A PROJECT AROUND AN
ISSUE?
FOR EXAMPLE, RAISING MONEY FOR
COMMUNITIES THAT NEED MONEY OR
FIGHTING FOR GUN LAWS, IF THAT'S
HOW THEY'RE SO MOVED?
>> THEY DO, BUT THERE'S A TIMING
TO IT.
IF YOU IMMEDIATELY GET INVOLVED
IN SOMETHING LIKE THAT, YOU
ACTUALLY MIGHT BE EVEN IN DENIAL
OF THE PAIN THAT YOU'RE FEELING.
YOU SHOULD FEEL THE PAIN
BECAUSE, IF YOU DON'T FEEL THE
PAIN, IT FESTERS.
>> YOU BROUGHT UP PAIN.
Y
YOU BROUGHT UP RAGE.
YOU BROUGHT UP ANGER.
IS IT OKAY TO FEEL ALL THOSE
THINGS?
>> YES, IT IS.
AT THIS MOMENT, IT IS.
>> DEEPAK CHOPRA, THANK YOU.
THERE ARE MANY GUN ADVOCATES WHO
FEEL THIS TRAGEDY COULD HAVE
BEEN PREVENTED HAD THE TEACHER
INSIDE THE SCHOOL BEEN ARMED?
COULD THAT HAVE HELPED?
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
IN LIGHT OF THIS TRAGEDY IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, IS IT TIME
TO ADDRESS THE NATION'S GUN
LAWS?
>> ONE OF THE PEOPLE SAYING IT
MOST LOUDLY IS NEW YORK MAYOR
MICHAEL BLOOMBERG.
>> THIS SHOULD BE HIS NUMBER ONE
AGENDA.
HE'S THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES, AND IF HE DOES NOTHING
DURING HIS SECOND TERM,
SOMETHING LIKE 48,000 AMERICANS
WILL BE KILLED WITH ILLEGAL
GUNS.
THAT IS ROUGHLY THE NUMBER OF
AMERICANS KILLED IN THE WHOLE
VIETNAM WAR.
>> MARK IS THE DIRECTOR OF
MAYORS AGAINST ILLEGAL GUNS.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US THIS
RNG MONT
MORNING.
>> THANKS FOR HAVING ME.
>> YOU HEARD MAYOR BLOOMBERG
RIGHT THERE.
OBVIOUSLY, THIS IS SOMETHING YOU
ARE PASSIONATE ABOUT.
WHAT IS YOUR NEXT ACTION?
>> IT TURNS OUT THERE'S A LOT
YOU CAN DO ABOUT NOT JUST MASS
SHOOTINGS LIKE THIS THAT ARE
TERRIBLE AND IMMEDIATE AND MAKE
THE HEADLINES, BUT ALSO THE 34
AMERICANS THAT ARE KILLED EVERY
DAY BY GUNS.
40% OF THE PEOPLE IN THIS
COUNTRY NEVER GET A BACKGROUND
CHECK WHEN THEY BUY A GUN.
WE FEEL THAT EVERYONE WHO BUYS A
GUN SHOULD GET A BACKGROUND
CHECK.
THAT'S SOMETHING 40% OF NRA
MEMBERS AGREE WITH.
SECONDLY, YOU HAVE TO TAKE A
LOOK AT AUTOMATIC HANDGUNS THAT
ALLOW PEOPLE TO FIRE A LOT OF
AMMUNITION IN A SHORT AMOUNT OF
TIME WITHOUT RELOADING.
AND YOU HAVE TO LOOK AT A
FEDERAL STATUTE THAT IMPOSES
REAL PENALTIES FOR STRAW
PURCHASING WHERE PEOPLE WHO CAN
BUY A GUN BECAUSE THEY HAVE A
CLEAN RECORD BUY FOR PEOPLE WHO
CAN'T, AND AS A RESULT, LOTS OF
GUNS END UP IN CRIMINAL HANDS.
>> THESE ARE MANY OF THE THINGS
WE HEAR ABOUT FREQUENTLY AS
WE'VE COVERED WAY TOO MANY OF
THESE TRAGEDIES.
I GUESS THE QUESTION FOR YOU IS
AFTER CHRISTMAS, WHEN IT GETS
BACK TO THE NEW YEAR, WHEN THE
LEGISLATORS COME BACK, WILL THIS
EMOTION STILL BE PALPABLE, AND
HOW DO YOU PLAN TO EFFECT THIS
CHANGE TO MAKE IT HAPPEN?
>> I THINK THIS IS DIFFERENT.
THERE ARE MOMENTS THAT MOST OF
US ARE OLD ENOUGH TO HAVE LIVED
THROUGH, AND IT FEELS LIKE
SOMETHING CHANGED.
I KNOW I FELT THAT WAY AFTER THE
OKLAHOMA CITY BOMBING.
EVERYBODY FELT THAT WAY AFTER
9/11.
AND ON THE ISSUE OF GUN
VIOLENCE, WITH THIS ESCALATING
AND RAPIDLY QUICKENING SERIES OF
MASS SHOOTINGS, I THINK THE
COUNTRY HAS REACHED A POINT
WHERE IT RECOGNIZES THE SCOPE OF
THE PROBLEM.
AND IS READY, NOT JUST TO MOVE
AGAINST THE KIND OF PROBLEMS
THAT CAUSE MASS SHOOTINGS LIKE
THIS TO DOMINATE THE HEADLINES,
BUT TO DEAL WITH THE KINDS OF
PROBLEMS, ONCE THE CAMERAS
LEAVE, THAT MURDER 34 PEOPLE
EVERY DAY.
AND THOSE MURDERS ARE NORMALLY
NOT DONE WITH ASSAULT RIFLES.
THEY'RE DONE WITH HANDGUNS.
AND MORE AND MORE OFTEN, THE
KIND OF JUNK HANDGUNS THAT ARE
INCREASINGLY POPULAR ON CITY
STREETS.
>> I GUESS I'M CURIOUS TO KNOW,
IF YOU THINK THAT SOMETHING IS
LIKELY TO HAPPEN.
BOTH JOHN AND I, AND I'M SURE
YOU'VE BEEN THROUGH THIS TOO,
BUT THE NRA IS A VERY POWERFUL
LOBBY.
THERE'S A REASON THEY GIVE A LOT
OF MONEY TO PEOPLE IN CONGRESS,
BOTH DEMOCRATS AND REPUBLICANS,
FRANKLY, WHO SUPPORT WHAT THEY
BELIEVE WHO ARE VERY MUCH
AGAINST ANY KIND OF STRONG BAN
ON WEAPONS.
HOW MUCH OF A FIGHT YOU'RE GOING
TO HAVE FROM THE NRA, WHICH IS
WELL FUNDED.
>> TWO POINTS ON THAT, SOLEDAD,
AND THE MAYOR MADE ONE OF THEM
ON TELEVISION YESTERDAY.
ONE OF THEM IS THERE'S A BIG
DIFFERENCE BETWEEN NRA MEMBERS
AND WHAT THEY WANT AND THE NRA
LOBBYISTS IN WASHINGTON AND WHAT
THEY WANT.
74% OF NRA MEMBERS THINK
EVERYBODY SHOULD GET A
BACKGROUND CHECK.
THAT'S SOMETHING THAT 82% OF GUN
OWNERS THINK.
71% OF NRA MEMBERS THINK THAT,
IF YOU'RE ON A TERROR WATCH LIST
AND YOU COULDN'T BOARD AN
AIRPLANE WITH ME THIS MORNING
WHEN I FLEW TO NEW YORK, YOU
SHOULDN'T BE ABLE TO HAVE A GUN.
SO THERE'S A BIG DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN WHAT THE RANK AND FILE
THINK AND WHAT THE NRA
LEADERSHIP THINKS.
I THINK THE LEADERSHIP IS GOING
TO START HEARING FROM THEIR RANK
AND FILE THAT THEY ACTUALLY WANT
TO BE REPRESENTED.
THE SECOND THING IS THE NRA HAS
DEVELOPED THIS REPUTATION FOR
BEING AN AWESOME POLITICAL FORCE
BECAUSE THEY GIVE A LOT OF MONEY
TO A LOT OF DIFFERENT
CANDIDATES, AND THERE HASN'T
BEEN MUCH POLITICAL GIVING ON
OUR SIDE OF THIS ISSUE, WHERE WE
THINK WE SHOULD SUPPORT THE
SECOND AMENDMENT, BUT ALSO DO
MORE TO PUT GUNS IN THE WRONG
HANDS.
I THINK THAT IS CHANGING.
I THINK WE NEED A LOT MORE
PEOPLE TO GET INVOLVED.
IF WE LOOK AT THE ELECTORAL
HISTORY OF THE NRA, THE NUMBER
OF POLITICAL RACES, WHERE
THEY'VE HAD A REAL AND
DISPOSITIVE INFLUENCE ON THE
NRA, IT'S MUCH MORE THAN IT'S
CRACKED UP TO BE, AND I THINK
MEMBERS OF CONGRESS ARE GOING TO
HAVE TO REALIZE THAT AND START
ACTING IN THE BEST INTERESTS OF
THE COUNTRY.
>> THERE ARE SOME PEOPLE WHO
MIGHT DISPUTE YOUR MATH ON THAT
ACTUALLY.
I THINK THERE ARE PLENTY OF
PEOPLE WHO SAY, NOT DEMONSTRATED
ON RACE, I'M NOT SURE EVERYBODY
WOULD AGREE WITH YOU.
MARK GLAZE IS THE DIRECTOR OF
MAYORS AGAINST ILLEGAL GUNS.
I WOULD BE CURIOUS TO FOLLOW
YOUR ACTIONS AND SEE WHAT IS
DONE AND WHAT TANGIBLE
DIFFERENCES ARE MADE.
AS ONCE AGAIN WE MOVE FROM THIS
TRAGEDY TO OTHER TRAGEDIES.
THANK YOU, SIR.
>>> STILL AHEAD THIS MORNING, A
SPECIAL MOMENT DURING LAST
NIGHT'S VIGIL AS THE PRESIDENT
WAS HONORING THE VICTIMS OF THE
NEWTOWN SHOOTING.
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA THINS
PACK THE BIG TASTE
OF GRANOLA AND DARK CHOCOLATE
INTO ONE PERFECT SQUARE,
UNDER 100 CALORIES.
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA THINS.
(Announcer) When Subaru owners
look in the mirror,
UNDER 100 CALORIES.
they see more than themselves.
So we celebrate our year-end
with the "share the love" event.
Get a great deal on a new Subaru
and 250 dollars goes to your
choice of five charities.
By the end of this, our fifth
year,
our total can reach almost 25
million dollars.
It's a nice reflection on us
all.
Now through January 2nd.
WHY THEY HAVE A
RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
TONIGHT OUR GUEST,
THOMAS SARGENT.
NOBEL LAUREATE
IN ECONOMICS,
AND ONE OF THE MOST CITED
ECONOMISTS IN THE WORLD.
PROFESSOR SARGENT,
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT CD RATES WILL
BE IN TWO YEARS?
NO.
IF HE CAN'T, NO ONE CAN.
THAT'S WHY ALLY HAS
A RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
ALLY BANK.
YOUR MONEY NEEDS AN ALLY.