>> WHY DID YOU GO BACK TO
COVERING WAR?
I WOULD THINK THAT WOULD MAKE
YOU NEVER EVER DO THAT AGAIN.
>> YOU ALWAYS THINK YOU CAN
MANAGE THE RISKS.
>> THANKS SO MUCH.
WE HAVE TO TAKE A BREAK.
WE'RE GOING TO HAND IT OFF TO
"CNN NEWSROOM" AND DON LEMON.
SEE EVERYBODY BACK HERE MONDAY
MORNING.
DON, GOOD MORNING.
>> HAVE A GREAT WEEKEND AS WELL.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
>>> HAPPENING NOW IN "THE
NEWSROOM" A CRUMBLING REGIME,
THE THREAT OF CHEMICAL WEAPONS.
THE U.S. RUSHES TO PROTECT AN
ALLY THAT SHARES A BORDER WITH
SYRIA.
>>> SUSAN RICE BOWS OUT.
JOHN KERRY GETS A LOT OF BUZZ.
WHO WILL BE THE NEXT SECRETARY
OF STATE.
>>> IT WORKS LIKE A PRINTER AND
PLASTIC PARTS.
SOME WORRY IT WILL MAKE PLASTIC
GUNS.
♪ WE'VE BEEN IN THE SKY FOR OUR
LOVE ♪
--
>> WHAT'S UP?
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
>> IMAGINE THAT, WHAT WOULD YOU
DO IF STEVIE WONDER WALKED INTO
YOUR RECORDING SESSION.
C "EN NEWSROOM" STARTS RIGHT
NOW.
GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE, FROM
WASHINGTON, I'M DON LEMON.
CAROL IS OFF TODAY.
WE BEGIN THIS HOUR WITH
SPIRALING CONCERNS OVER SYRIA
AND A DESPERATE REGIME TRYING TO
HOLD ON TO POWER.
THIS MORNING, WASHINGTON
ANNOUNCES IT'S DEPLOYING TWO
PATRIOT MISSILE BATTERIES AND
400 TROOPS TO OUR NATO ALLY
TURKEY.
IT WILL BOLSTER DEFENSES TO
SYRIA AGAINST ITS SCUD MISSILES
AND POSSIBLE CHEMICAL WEAPONS.
>> IT'S A CHALLENGING TIME.
IT'S A CHALLENGING TIME.
IT'S A CRITICAL TIME.
WE JUST ANNOUNCED, JUST
ANNOUNCED THIS MORNING THAT WE
ARE DEPLOYING TWO PATRIOT
BATTERIES HERE TO TURKEY, ALONG
WITH THE TROOPS THAT ARE
NECESSARY TO MAN THOSE BATTERIES
SO THAT WE CAN HELP TURKEY HAVE
THE KIND OF MISSILE DEFENSE IT
MAY VERY WELL NEED IN DEALING
WITH THREATS THAT COME OUT OF
SYRIA.
>> TO CNN'S NICK PATON WALSH IN
BEIRUT FOLLOWING THE LATEST
DEVELOPMENTS.
NICK IS ON THE PHONE, WHAT CAN
YOU TELL US?
>> WE DON'T KNOW THE EXACT
LOCATION WHERE THE AMERICAN
TROOPS ARE GOING TO BE STATIONED
BUT THE GERMAN PARLIAMENT
RATIFIED PART OF ITS
CONTRIBUTION, THERE WILL BE
THREE NATO NATIONS GIVING TROOPS
TOWARD THIS.
THE U.S. TWO BATTERIES AND 400
TROOPS, THE GERMANS ARE EXPECTED
TO MAKE A SIMILAR CONTRIBUTION
AS WELL AS THE NETHERLANDS AS
WELL.
IT PUTS NATO FORCES IN THE
VOLUME TIRE AREA.
THE BACK STORY HOW WE GOT TO
HERE TWO MONTHS AGO THERE WERE
EXCHANGES OF FIRE, THE SYRIAN
ARMY ACCUSED OF SHELLING AREAS
INSIDE TURKEY, CAUSING
DESTRUCTION AND INJURY TO
TURKEY, AND TURKEY FIRING BACK
AND ASKING FOR NATO BACKUP.
THERE WAS NEVER ANY DOUBT NATO
WOULD COME TO TURKEY.
WE HAVE A SUBSTANTIAL MANPOWER
AND WEAPONRY RIGHT ON THE SYRIAN
BORDER.
NATO VERY CLEAR IT'S PURELY FOR
DEFENSE OF TURKEY, NOT MEANT TO
ENFORCE WHAT PEOPLE ARE SAYING
MIGHT BE A NO FLY ZONE.
YOU HEART SECRETARY OF DEFENSE
LEON PA NET TA, CONCERNS OF
CHEMICAL WEAPONS USE.
THE U.S. HAS A PLAN TO RESPOND.
NOT CLEAR IF PATRIOTS WILL BE
INVOLVED BUT CERTAINLY IN THIS
21-MONTH-LONG REVOLT, NATO, THE
BIGGEST MACHINERY IN THE WORLD
IN THAT VOLATILE AREA.
>> NICK PATON WALSH, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
>>> IN WASHINGTON A WITHDRAWAL
AND A SURRENDER.
AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE DROPS OUT
OF THE RUNNING FOR SECRETARY OF
STATE.
THE JOB SEEMED TO BE HERS BUT
THEN THERE WAS A DEAD LAY TACK
ON ITS U.S. CONSULATE IN LIBYA,
DAYS AFTER U.S. AMBASSADOR CHRIS
STEVENS AND THREE OTHER
ERICANS WERE KILLED, RICE SAID
IT WAS A SPONTANEOUS PROTEST
THAT GOT OUT OF HAND RATHER THAN
A PLANNED TERRORIST ATTACK.
REPUBLICANS SAY SHE WAS LYING TO
DOWNPLAY HER BOSS'S FAILED
POLICIES.
RICE DEFENDS HER HANDLING EVEN
NOW.
>> I WAS VERY CAREFUL TO EXPLAIN
THAT THE INFORMATION WAS
PRELIMINARY, AND IT COULD CHANGE
AND YET I THINK IT WAS
MISCONSTRUED AND CONTORTED INTO
SOMETHING MUCH MORE NEFARIOUS
THAT WAS NEVER INDEED THE CASE
NOR MY INTENTION.
>> WELL THE BACKLASH AGAINST
RICE ONLY GREW AFTER SHE MET
WITH CONCERNED LAWMAKERS BEHIND
CLOSE DOORS.
THE ODDS OF A CONFIRMATION HAD
GROWN SO BLEAK THE WHITE HOUSE
NEVER WENT THROUGH A FORMAL
NOMINATION.
>> I HADN'T MADE A DECISION
ABOUT WHO WOULD BE MY NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE.
THERE'S NO DOUBT THAT SUSAN WAS
QUALIFIED.
THERE ARE OTHER PEOPLE WHO ARE
QUALIFIED AS WELL.
HER INTEREST IS IN SERVING ME,
BUT MOST IMPORTANTLY SERVING THE
COUNTRY AND SHE'S DONE AN
OUTSTANDING JOB.
I COULD NOT BE PROUDER WITH HER.
SHE WILL CONTINUE TO BE ONE OF
THE TOP MEMBERS OF MY NATIONAL
SECURITY TEAM.
>> WE ARE COVERING ALL ANGLES
WITH FOREIGN AFFAIRS REPORTER
ALYSE LAVITT AND BRIANNA KEILAR.
BRIANA, THE PRESIDENT WAS VOCAL
IN HIS SUPPORT.
AFTER TWO MONTHS, A LACK OF
CONFIDENCE HERE?
>> Reporter: I THINK DEFINITELY
THERE WAS A LACK OF CONFIDENCE,
THAT THIS WAS A FIGHT THAT THE
PRESIDENT WANTED TO HAVE RIGHT
NOW.
IT'S OBVIOUS THAT PRESIDENT
OBAMA HAS A GREAT AFFINITY FOR
AMBASSADOR RICE.
YOU CAN SEE THAT WHEN HE TALKS
ABOUT HER.
HE CAME TO HER DEFENSE IN THE
LAST MONTH QUITE A BIT BUT I
THINK THERE WAS A LOT OF CONCERN
ABOUT THE TIMING AND WHETHER
THIS WAS A FIGHT THAT HE WANTED
TO HAVE.
HE HAD SAID IN HIS FIRST, IN HIS
PRESS CONFERENCE FOLLOWING HIS
RE-ELECTION THAT IF HE THOUGHT
SHE WAS THE BEST PERSON FOR THE
JOB, THAT HE WOULD NOMINATE HER
BUT HE WENT ON TO NOT PIN
HIMSELF IN, NOT TO MAKE A
DECISION, AND SOME OF THE
CRITICS WHO WERE IN THE CORNER
OF SUSAN RICE SAY THIS MAY HAVE
ACTUALLY SEALED HER FATE.
SHE ENDED UP HEADING UP TO
CAPITOL HILL TRYING TO DEFEND
HERSELF AGAINST HER ROLE
IMMEDIATELY FOLLOWING WHAT
HAPPENED IN BENGHAZI AND TRYING
TO EXPLAIN THAT ON BEHALF OF THE
ADMINISTRATION.
WHEN SHE WENT UP TO CAPITOL HILL
TO MEET WITH LAWMAKERS THE
VISITS BACKFIRED.
THEY RAISED A LOT OF QUESTIONS
AND SHE WAS THERE TO TRY TO
ANSWER THEM AND TRY TO ASSUAGE
CONCERNS, THAT WAS TRUE WITH
SENATOR SUSAN HOLLINS OF MAINE,
A REPUBLICAN BUT A MODERATE AND
THAT WAS SEEN AS VERY TROUBLING
IN ALL OF THIS PROCESS.
SOME CRITIC ALSO SAY, DON, THAT
WITHOUT THE NOMINATION, SHE WAS
LEFT TWISTING IN THE WIND BUT
THERE'S ALSO THIS SENSE THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS A WHOLE LOT
ON HIS PLATE.
HE'S OBVIOUSLY INVOLVED IN THIS
FIGHT OVER THE STRIKING A DEAL
ON THE FISCAL CLIFF, AND THEN
GOING INTO NEXT YEAR, A LOT OF
GOALS OBVIOUSLY TO FOLLOW ON
THAT ENTITLEMENT REFORM,
SPENDING CUTS, TAX REFORM AND
DON'T FORGET IMMIGRATION REFORM
IS ALSO A PRIORITY, SO I THINK
THERE WAS A SENSE THAT DO YOU
REALLY SPEND ALL OF THIS
POLITICAL CAPITAL ON THIS FIGHT
WHEN THERE'S SO MANY OTHER
THINGS TO DO.
>> AND SO SHE REFERENCED THAT AS
WELL IN HER LETTER THAT SHE PUT
OUT YESTERDAY.
ALYSE, YOU COVER THE STATE
DEPARTMENT.
WHO IS ON THE SHORT LIST TO BE
NOMINATED HERE?
JOHN KERRY OF COURSE.
>> WELL, DON, HE'S REALLY THE
ONLY NAME ON THE SHORT LIST.
SENATOR KERRY AS THE CHAIR OF
THE SENATE FOREIGN RELATIONS
COMMITTEE HAS A LOT OF WORLD
STATURE, HAS A LOT OF
RELATIONSHIPS WITH WORLD LEADERS
AND IN THE PAST HE'S REALLY DONE
A LOT FOR PRESIDENT OBAMA.
IF YOU REMEMBER, WHEN JOHN KERRY
WAS RUNNING FOR PRESIDENT IN
2004, HE GAVE THEN SENATOR OBAMA
HIS FIRST KIND OF SHOT ON THE
WORLD STAGE AT THE DEMOCRATIC
CONVENTION.
HE'S ALSO BEEN PRESIDENT OBAMA'S
PARTNER IN TERMS OF PREPPING FOR
THE DEBATE.
HE SERVED IN AS MITT ROMNEY, AND
ALSO SENATOR KERRY HAS ALSO DONE
A LOT OF WORK FOR THE
ADMINISTRATION IN TERMS OF
TROUBLESHOOTING AROUND THE
WORLD.
THIS GUY GOT AFGHAN PRESIDENT
HAMID KARZAI TO AGREE TO A
RUNOFF ELECTION.
HE MEETS WITH THE PAKISTANIS
WHENEVER THERE IS A PROBLEM, MET
WITH BASHAR AL ASSAD AT ONE
POINT.
SO HE'S REALLY SEEN AS ALTHOUGH
SUSAN RICE WAS SEEN AS SOMEONE
WHO COULD HAVE BEEN THE
PRESIDENT'S FIRST CHOICE HE'S
CERTAINLY A CANDIDATE THAT IS UP
TO THE TASK AND HAS A LOT OF
FOREIGN POLICY CREDIBILITY
AROUND THE WORLD.
DON?
>> ELISE LABOTT AND BRIANNA
KEILAR THANKS OBOTH OF YOU.
>>> WHEN IT COMES TO THE FISCAL
CLIFF STILL NO DEAL AND NOW THE
DEBT CEILING IS CAUGHT IN THE
CROSS-FIRE HERE.
SPECIFICALLY A PART OF THE WHITE
HOUSE'S FISCAL CLIFF PLAN THAT
WOULD GIVE THE PRESIDENT THE
POWER TO INCREASE THE DEBT LIMIT
WITHOUT CONGRESS THAT IS.
BOEHNER MAKING IT CLEAR THAT IT
IS NOT UP FOR A DEBATE.
>> DO YOU THINK THAT SENATOR
REID OR THEN SENATOR OBAMA WOULD
HAVE EVER GIVEN TO PRESIDENT
GEORGE W. BUSH THE UNLIMITED
ABILITY TO RAISE THE DEBT LIMIT?
I KNOW THEY'RE TALKING ABOUT
DOING IT NOW.
DO YOU THINK THERE'S ANY CHANCE
THAT SENATOR REID OR THEN
SENATOR OBAMA WOULD HAVE DONE
THAT?
ZERO.
CONGRESS IS NEVER GOING TO GIVE
UP OUR ABILITY TO CONTROL THE
PURSE.
>> SO FOR PRESIDENT OBAMA'S
PART, HE IS DIGGING IN AS WELL
ON AN AREA THAT HAS BEEN KEY
STICKING POINT AND THAT'S TAXES.
>> THE MOST IMPORTANT THING WE
CAN DO RIGHT NOW IS MAKE SURE
THAT MIDDLE CLASS TAXES DO NOT
GO UP.
THAT'S THE BEST THING FOR THE
ECONOMY, BEST THING FOR AMERICAN
FAMILIES AND IF WE DO THAT,
SENATE'S ALREADY PASSED THIS
BILL.
HOUSE DEMOCRATS ARE READY TO
PASS T I'M READY TO SIGN IT.
THE ONLY HOLDOUTS ARE THE HOUSE
REPUBLICANS.
IF WE GET THAT DONE THAT WILL
TAKE THE EDGE OFF THINGS.
WE'LL STILL HAVE TO DEAL WITH
DEFICIT AND DEBT PROBLEMS.
98% OF AMERICANS, 97% OF SMALL
BUSINESSES WILL NOT SEE THEIR
TAXES GO UP.
WE SHOULD GET THAT DONE.
>> THE HOUSE IS SCHEDULED TO GO
HOME FOR THE YEAR TODAY BUT
HOUSE MAJORITY LEADER ERIC
CANTOR SAYS MEMBERS COULD BE
WORKING LONGER WITH THE FISCAL
CLIFF STILL UNRESOLVED.
>>> DO YOU KNOW THIS MAN?
IT COULD BE WORTH $5,000 TO YOU.
THE FBI IS HOPING THE REWARD
WILL LEAD TO AN ARREST OF A
ROBBER WHO HAS HIT 13 BANKS FROM
VIRGINIA TO CALIFORNIA.
HE'S BEING CALLED THE RAY BANDIT
BECAUSE OF HIS BIG SUNGLASSES
AND DIFFERING DISGUISES.
>>> A FUNNY MOMENT FROM THE
CINCINNATI BENGALS -- FILL
EAGLES GAME.
THE HELMETS OF ANDRE SMITH AND
BRANDON GRAHAM GOT STUCK
TOGETHER.
THE REF HAD TO HELP SEPARATE
HEM.
GRAHAM CHUCKLED ABOUT IT.
THE WOEFUL EAGLES DIDN'T HAVE
MUCH MORE TO LAUGH ABOUT IN THIS
GAME, FIVE TURNOVERS AND LOST TO
THE BENGALS 34-13.
>>> TWO 11-YEAR-OLD BOYS, THAT
TROPHY THEY'RE HOLDING IS 13,000
YEARS OLD, 13,000 YEARS OLD.
BECAUSE IT'S FROM TROY,
MICHIGAN, THEY WERE SCOURING A
CREEK STUMBLED ACROSS A BONE
FROM A MACEDON, AN ELEPHANT LIKE
BEAST THAT DIED 10,000 YEARS
AGO.
THEY'RE CALLING IT THE COOLEST
SHOW AND TELL ITEM EVER.
>>> YOU CAN MAKE PART OF A
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE USING A 3-D
PRINTER.
LAWMAKERS FEAR IT'S A MATTER OF
TIME BEFORE PEOPLE START MAKING
HOMEMADE GUNS.
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
HOW THEY'LL LIVE TOMORROW.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
>>> CHECKING OUR TOP STORIES FOR
YOU NOW WE HAVE NEW VIDEO OF THE
CRASH THAT KILLED DALLAS COWBOY
JERRY BROWN JR., LED TO A
MANSLAUGHTER INVESTIGATION
AGAINST HIS TEAMMATE JOSH BRENT
SHOWN ON THE RIGHT.
911 TAPES SHOW WITNESSES
FRANTICALLY CALLING FOR HELP
EARLY SATURDAY MORNING NEAR
DALLAS.
>> IS IT S ANYBODY INJURED?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
I JUST DROVE PAST IT, IT LOOKED
LIKE IT JUST HAPPENED, THERE WAS
A CAR UPSIDE DOWN AND THERE WAS
SMOKE EVERYWHERE.
>> BRENT WAS ARRESTED AND
ACCUSED OF DRIVING DRUNK.
FAMILY MEMBERS SAY HE AND BROWN
WERE BEST FRIENDS.
>>> THE MALL IN OREGON WHERE THE
SHOOTING RAMPAGE TOOK PLACE WILL
REOPEN IN A FEW HOURS.
TUESDAY A MAN SHOT AND KILLED
TWO PEOPLE IN A RAMPAGE AND
KILLED HIMSELF.
SEVERAL MALL WORKERS SAY THEY'RE
HESITANT ABOUT RETURNING TO THE
MALL.
>>> ATTORNEY GENERAL ERIC HOLDER
FACING HARSH CRITICISM FROM A
TOP REPUBLICAN AFTER FAILING TO
PURSUE CRIMINAL CHARGES AGAINST
HSBC.
THE BANK ADMITS LAUNDERING MONEY
FROM IRAN, LIBYA AND MYANMAR.
CHUCK GRASSLEY CALLS THE LACK OF
CHARGES A DECLARATION THAT
"CRIME DOES PAY."
THE JUSTICE DEPARTMENT DID NOT
COMMENT BUT DEFENDS ITS NEARLY
$2 BILLION SETTLEMENT WITH THE
BANK.
>>> TWO MASSACHUSETTS COSTCO
WORKERS ARE SPLITTING A $50
MILLION POWERBALL PRIZE.
ROSA DELEON BUYS TWO TICKETS
EVERY DAY AND SHARES THEM WITH
HER CO-WORKER REGINALD.
ON WEDNESDAY THE TICKETS FINALLY
PAID OFF.
THE TWO WILL EACH GET $11
MILLION AFTER TAXES.
CONGRATULATIONS TO THEM.
VERY LUCKY.
>>> THERE IS A MACHINE THAT
COULD ONE DAY BE USED TO MAKE
HOMEMADE GUNS, NOT ONLY THAT, IT
COULD MAKE PLASTIC GUNS THAT A
METAL DETECTOR WON'T FIND.
YOU CAN BELIEVE SOME PEOPLE ARE
WORRIED ABOUT IT.
HERE IS JOE JOHNS WITH MORE.
>> Reporter: IN THE THIS
NORTHERN VIRGINIA GUN STORE YOU
CAN BUY ALL SORTS OF WEAPONS BUT
WHAT IF YOU COULD MAKE WEAPONS
IN YOUR OWN HOME USING A
THREE-DIMENSIONAL PRINTER.
SOUNDS LIKE SCIENCE FICTION BUT
TO SOME IT'S NOT FAR-FETCHED.
>> PRIMARILY 3-D PRINTERS ARE
USED TO MANUFACTURE PARTS FOR
ANTIQUE CARS.
>> YOU THINK OUR KILLER PRINTED
A GUN.
>> MULTIPLE GUNS, IDENTICAL
DISPOSABLE UNTRACEABLE.
>> Reporter: IT COULD ALSO BE
UNDETECTABLE.
3-D PRINTERS MAKE SOLID OBJECTS
FROM DIGITAL MODELS AND PLANS
AND WHAT'S MANUFACTURED COULD BE
ALL PLASTIC LIKE THIS LITTLE
GADGET WITH ALL THESE MOVING
PARTS THAT WORK TOGETHER
PERFECTLY.
SO A PLASTIC GUN MANUFACTURED
WITH THIS TECHNOLOGY MIGHT NOT
NECESSARILY BE PICKED UP BY YOUR
GARDEN VARIETY METAL DETECTOR AT
AN AIRPORT OR PUBLIC BUILDING.
IT'S A POTENTIAL GAME CHANGER IN
THE GUN CONTROL DEBATE.
>> WE'RE TRYING TO PRODUCE GUNS
WITH THIS TECHNOLOGY.
>> Reporter: ADVOCATES OF THE
PRINTABLE GUN LIKE UNIVERSITY OF
TEXAS STUDENT CODY WILSON SEE IT
AS A RIGHTS ISSUE.
>> I BELIEVE IN THE UNIVERSAL
ACCESS TO ARMS AND AS FAR AS
IT'S POSSIBLE FOR ME THIS WILL
BE COMPLETELY UNABLE TO BE
REGULATED.
>> Reporter: HE'S BEHIND DEFENSE
DISTRIBUTED, A NONPROFIT
ORGANIZATION DEDICATED TO
CREATING WHAT WILSON CALLED THE
WIKIWEAPON, A FIREARM WITH A
DESIGN THAT CAN BE DISTRIBUTED
ON THE INTERNET AND MANUFACTURED
USING A 3-D PRINTER.
HE'S ALREADY BUILT PART OF AN
AR-15 USING THE TECHNOLOGY.
DEMOCRATIC CONGRESSMAN STEVE
ISRAEL HAS TAKEN NOTICE.
>> I WANT TO MAKE IT IMPOSSIBLE
FOR PEOPLE TO USE
THREE-DIMENSIONAL PRINTERS TO
MANUFACTURE GUN COMPONENTS WHICH
WAS DONE AND SIX BULLETS WERE
FIRED FROM ONE OF THESE
COMPONENTS.
>> Reporter: THAT'S WHY
CONGRESSMAN ISRAEL IS PUSHING TO
RENEW THE UNDETECTABLE FIREARMS
ACT A LAW PASSED A QUARTER OF A
CENTURY AGO BANNING PLASTIC
FIREARMS THAT WILL EXPIRE NEXT
YEAR.
>> DEFIES COMMON SENSE, SAFETY
AND LOGIC TO MAKE IT EASIER FOR
CRIMINALS TO MANUFACTURE THE
COMPONENTS OF GUNS WHICH COULD
BE BROUGHT ON TO OUR PLANES AND
BUILDINGS.
>> Reporter: PRO GUN ADVOCATES
SAY TO DATE NO ONE USING A 3-D
PRINTER HAS MANUFACTURED A
WORKING FIREARM COMPLETELY OUT
OF PLASTIC.
ONE 3-D PRINTING EXPERT SAYS IT
MIGHT NOT EVEN BE POSSIBLE ANY
TIME SOON.
>> I DON'T FEEL THIS TECHNOLOGY
IS GOING TO BE THERE NEXT YEAR
BUT IN MY ESTIMATION WE HAVE
TIME AND WAYS TO GO TO GET
THERE.
>> Reporter: WILSON WORRIES
ABOUT THE CHILLING EFFECT OF NEW
IDEAS.
MR. ISRAEL SAYS WE SHOULD
PREVENT THE DEVELOPMENT OF A
WHOLE BRANCH OF TECHNOLOGY.
HE'S RIDICULOUS.
>>> DON'T COUNT THE TWINKIE OUT
JUST YET.
WHICH BIG NAMED COMPANIES MAY BE
BIDDING ON HOSTESS, THE ICONIC
SNACKMAKER.
PEOPLE HAVE DOUBTS
ABOUT TAKING ASPIRIN FOR PAIN.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
>>> IF YOU THOUGHT TWINKIES AND
DING DONGS WEREONE FOR GOOD,
THERE'S STILL HOPE.
TWO FAMILIAR FACES HAVE EMERGED
AS POTENTIAL BIDDERS FOR THE NOW
BANKRUPT HOSTESS COMPANY.
MARIBAL, WHO ARE THE POTENTIAL
BUYERS?
>> THERE'S STILL HOPE.
THERE ARE ABOUT TWO DOZEN
BIDDERS, WALMART AND KROGER IN
THE MIX, OTHER FIRST ROUND
BIDDERS, GROUPO BIMBO, AND ALPHA
BAKING COMPANY.
IT'S JUST TALK RIGHT NOW, DON,
BUT THIS IS EXACTLY WHAT WE
EXPECTED THE MAKER OF TWINKIES
AND DING DONGS IS IN THE PROCESS
OF LIQUIDATING.
THE COMPANY CAN BE CHOPPED OFF
AND SOLD OFF IN BUSINESSES.
SINCE HOSTESS IS BANKRUPT THE
PIECES COME AT ROCK BOTTOM
PRICES.
MAKES TWINKIES AN ATTRACTIVE
BUY.
>> WHAT IS THE LIKELIHOOD
MARIBEL THE BRANDS WILL SURVIVE?
>> PRETTY GOOD.
THERE'S STILL VALUE, TWINKIE,
DING DONGS, HO-HOS.
BEFORE THEY WENT UNDER THEY HAD
$2 ABOUTLE IN ANNUAL SALES.
THERE'S STILL A MARKET.
THE PROBLEM WITH HOSTESS WAS
THEIR COST STRUCTURE.
THEY HAD PLANTS SPREAD ACROSS
DOZENS OF STATES, NOT EXACTLY
EFFICIENT AND THE COMPANIES SAID
LABOR COSTS WERE THE MAJOR
ISSUES.
WE MIGHT SEE IT START TO PLAY
OUT, THE LAST BATCH OF TWINKIES
HIT STORES IN CHICAGO THIS WEEK.
THE LINES THEY WERE OUT THE DOOR
AND WEDNESDAY THEY WERE ALL SOLD
OUT.
>> MARIBEL THANK YOU VERY MUCH,
APPRECIATE IT.
>>> A CRITICAL DAY FOR HEALTH
CARE REFORM AS STATES DECIDE TO
TAKE PART IN A KEY PORTION OF
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S AFFORDABLE
CARE ACT.
WE'LL EXPLAIN HOW IT COULD
AFFECT YOU.
So now I can be in
the scene.
ADVAIR is
clinically proven to help
significantly improve
lung function.
Unlike most COPD medications,
ADVAIR contains both an
anti-inflammatory
and a
long-acting bronchodilator
working together to help improve
your lung function all day.
ADVAIR won't
replace fast-acting inhalers
for sudden symptoms
and should not be used more
than twice a day.
People with
COPD taking ADVAIR
may have a higher chance
of pneumonia.
ADVAIR may increase your
risk of osteoporosis
and some eye problems.
Tell your doctor
if you have a heart condition
or high blood pressure before
taking ADVAIR.
If you're still
having difficulty breathing,
ask your doctor if including
ADVAIR could help
improve your lung function.
Get your
first full
prescription
free
and save
on refills
at
ADVAIRcopd.com.
AND HIS NEW BOSS TOLD HIM
TWO THINGS --
COOK WHAT YOU LOVE,
AND SAVE YOUR MONEY.
JOE DOESN'T KNOW IT YET,
BUT HE'LL WORK HIS WAY UP
FROM BUSSER TO WAITER TO CHEF
BEFORE OPENING A RESTAURANT
SPECIALIZING IN FISH AND GAME
FROM THE GREAT NORTHWEST.
HE'LL START INVESTING EARLY,
HE'LL FIND SOME GOOD PEOPLE
TO HELP GUIDE HIM,
AND HE'LL SET MONEY ASIDE
FROM HIS FIRST DAY OF WORK
TO HIS LAST,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
>>> GOOD MORNING I'M.LEMON.
STORIES IN THE NEWSROOM, OPENING
BELL TO RING SOON ON WALL
STREET, WE SHOULD HEAR IT ANY
SECOND.
STOCKS ARE SET TO OPEN HIGHER
TODAY FOLLOWING NEWS THAT
MANUFACTURING IS PICKING UP IN
CHINA.
GAINS ARE EXPECTED TO BE MODEST,
THOUGH AS THE FISCAL CLIFF ISSUE
REMAINS UNRESOLVED.
>>> THE U.S. IS SHOWING ITS
SUPPORT FOR TURKEY IN THE FACE
OF POTENTIAL THREATS FROM SYRIA.
THE U.S. MILLTORY WILL DEPLOY
400 TROOPS TO TURKEY IN THE
COMING WEEKS.
THE PATRIOT THE MISSILE SYSTEM
WOULD BE USED ONLY FOR DEFENSE.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA IS SPEAKING
OUT ABOUT MARRIAGE MARRIAGE FOR
THE FIRST TIME SINCE COLORADO
AND WASHINGTON STATE LEGALIZED
IT.
HE TOLD ABC'S BARBARA WALTERS HE
DISCOURAGES DRUG USE AND REGRETS
DOING IT AS A KID BUT SAYS IT'S
NOT A TOP PRIORITY FOR THE FEDS
TO PROSECUTE RECREATIONAL USERS
IN STATES THAT HAVE LEGALIZED
THE SUBSTANCE.
>>> WE'RE AWAITING WORD ON THE
NEXT ROUND OF FISCAL CLIFF
NEGOTIATIONS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER METAPHOR
JUST UNDER AN HOUR AT THE WHITE
HOUSE LATE YESTERDAY AFTERNOON.
STILL NO DEAL.
AIDES FOR BOTH MEN DESCRIBE THE
SESSION AS FRANK AND SAY THE
LINES OF COMMUNICATION WILL STAY
OPEN.
THE LAW OF THE LAND, THAT'S HOW
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER
DESCRIBED THE AFFORDABLE CARE
ACT, IT OVERHAULED THE NATION'S
HEALTH CARE SYSTEM AND TODAY
MARKS A CRITICAL MILESTONE IN
THE IMPLEMENTATION OF THAT ACT.
STATES MUST DECIDE WHETHER THEY
WILL SET UP THEIR OWN EXCHANGES
WHICH WILL REQUIRE RESIDENTS TO
SELECT A HEALTH CARE PLAN.
OUR SENIOR MEDICAL CORRESPONDENT
ELIZABETH COHEN JOINS ME WITH
MORE.
WHAT ARE THE EXCHANGES AND HOW
DO THEY WORK?
>> AN EXCHANGE IS YOU GO ONLINE
AND YOU BUY INSURANCE BECAUSE
THE WHOLE POINT OF OBAMA CARE IS
EVERY AMERICAN IS SUPPOSED TO BE
INSURED BY THE TIME THIS IS
DONE.
SO LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT THE
BASICS OF THE EXCHANGES.
IT'S FOR PEOPLE WHO ARE NOT
GETTING THEIR INSURANCE THROUGH
THEIR EMPLOYER AND THE
PROVIDERS, THE INSURERS HAVE TO
TAKE YOU.
THEY CAN'T TELL YOU NO BECAUSE
THEY HAVE A PREEXISTING
CONDITION AND CAN'T CHARGE YOU
MORE WHICH IS A HUGE CHANGE FROM
THE WAY IT IS NOW AND YOU WILL
GET A SUBSIDY TO HELP YOU BUY
THAT INSURANCE IF YOUR FAMILY
MAKES UNDER APPROXIMATELY
$92,000 FOR A FAMILY OF FOUR.
NOW YOU WERE REFERRING TO WHO IS
GOING TO RUN THESE EXCHANGES?
LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT A MAP.
THIS MAP SHOWS THE STATES IN
GREEN HAVE BASICALLY TOLD THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT WE WANT TO
YOU DO IT.
YOU GUYS ORGANIZE THESE AND RUN
THESE.
THE STATES IN WHITE ARE GOING TO
RUN THEIR OWN EXCHANGES ON THEIR
OWN OR THEY'VE TEAMED UP WITH
OTHER STATES.
DON?
>> ALL RIGHT, ELIZABETH COHEN,
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
JOINING ME NOW IS JOEL ARIO,
FORMER DIRECTOR WITH THE
DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN
SERVICES AND CURRENTLY MANAGING
DIRECTOR OF MEN AT HEALTH
SOLUTIONS.
JOE YOU ALSO WORKED AS INSURANCE
COMMISSIONER IN PENNSYLVANIA AND
OREGON.
FROM YOUR EXPERIENCE, YOU SAY
THERE ARE A FEW REASONS WHY
STATES SHOULD SET UP THE
EXCHANGES.
WHAT ARE THEY?
>> I THINK THERE ARE TWO MAIN
REASONS AND RELATE TO PROGRAMS
THAT STATES HAVE TRADITIONAL
MANAGED THEMSELVES.
THE FIRST IS THE COMMERCIAL
INSURANCE MARKETS STATES HAVE
FOR MORE THAN A CENTURY NOW
MANAGED THEIR OWN COMMERCIAL
INSURANCE MARKET AND THAT MEANS
SINCE THE HEALTH CARE REALLY
BECAME A BIG DEAL IN THE 1950s,
STATES HAVE PRIMARILY BEEN IN
CHARGE OF THAT MARKET.
THE EXCHANGES FIT INTO THAT
MARKET AND IF STATES MAINTAIN
CONTROL OVER THE EXCHANGES, THEY
THEN HAVE A COORDINATED
ENFORCEMENT AND IMPLEMENTATION
OF LAWS ACROSS THE COMMERCIAL
MARKETPLACE.
IF THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT COMES
IN AND RUNS THIS PARTICULAR
PROGRAM, THEN THERE GET TO BE
COORDINATION ISSUES, TWO LEVELS
OF GOVERNMENT DIRECTLY INVOLVED
IN THE DAY-TO-DAY ACTIVITY AND
THAT'S PROBABLY NOT IN THE END
GOOD FOR THE CONSUMER.
THE SECOND REASON IS THE STATE
MEDICAID PROGRAMS, THE EXCHANGES
WORK BOTH FOR PEOPLE TO GET
COMMERCIAL TAX CREDITS IF
THEY'RE ABOVE 138% OF POVERTY
BUT LESS THAN 400% OF POVERTY
SHALL.
IF THEY'RE BELOW 138% OF
POVERTY, THEY HAVE COVERAGE
UNDER THE MEDICAID PROGRAM, SO
AGAIN, IF STATES ARE RUNNING THE
MEDICAID PROGRAM AND THE
EXCHANGES, THERE CAN BE A MORE
COORDINATED APPROACH AS PEOPLE
MOVE BACK AND FORTH BETWEEN
THEM, IF THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT
RUNS THE EXCHANGE AND THE STATE
RUNS THE MEDICAID PROGRAM, THEN
THERE'S AGAIN SOME HANDOFFS AND
POTENTIAL FOR THE CONSUMER TO BE
NOT AS WELL SERVED.
I DO THINK THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT WILL DO A GOOD JOB
BUT THEY -- EXCUSE ME --
>> THAT'S ALL RIGHT YOUR PHONE
WENT OFF.
>> THEY DO HAVE A MORE DIFFICULT
TIME IF THE STATE, IF THERE'S A
COORDINATION BETWEEN THE TWO
PROGRAMS.
>> LET ME JUMP IN HERE BECAUSE
EVERYTHING YOU'RE SAYING SOUNDS
COMPLICATED.
I DON'T KNOW HOW PEOPLE ARE
GOING TO FIGURE THIS OUT.
OBVIOUSLY YOU'RE AN EXPERT HERE
BUT ON TO SOMETHING THAT'S IN
MORE LAYMAN'S TERMS HERE, WHAT
ABOUT THE ARGUMENT THAT THIS IS
AN EXAMPLE OF THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT INTERFERING WITH
STATE CONTROL.
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THAT?
>> IF YOU LOOK AT THE WAY HEALTH
INSURANCE WORKS TODAY IT'S A
RICH MIX OF STATE AND FEDERAL
CONTROL.
WE DO LIKE THE FACT THAT UNDER
FEDERAL LAW CONSUMER PRIVACY IS
PROTECTED UNDER A LAW THAT
PASSED IN 1996.
THERE ARE A NUMBER OF OTHER
FEDERAL LAW THAT PASSED, ONE
THAT REQUIRES STATES TO MAKE
SURE THAT IN THE SMALL GROUP
MARKET NOBODY CAN BE EXCLUDED,
NO BUSINESS CAN BE EXCLUDED
BECAUSE THEY HAVE ONE SICK
PERSON.
NOW THAT FEDERAL REQUIREMENT IS
BEING EXTENDED TO THE INDIVIDUAL
MARKET, SO THERE ARE SOME NEW
FEDERAL REGULATIONS IN THIS
PROGRAM BUT IT'S NOT A NEW
PRECEDENT.
TODAY THE STATE OFFICIALS WHEN I
WAS INSURANCE COMMISSIONER IN
PENNSYLVANIA I ENFORCED BOTH
STATE AND FEDERAL LAW, WHAT MOST
MATTERED TO ME WAS MY ABILITY TO
ENFORCE THAT LAW TO THE BENEFIT
OF CONSUMERS ACROSS THE
COMMERCIAL MARKETPLACE, AND EVEN
THOUGH SOME OF IT WAS ENFORCED
IN FEDERAL LAW IT STILL WAS THE
DAY-TO-DAY CONTROL WAS WITH ME
AND MY DEPARTMENT IN
PENNSYLVANIA.
>> JOEL ARIO, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
APPRECIATE YOU COMING ON.
>>> HE'S KNOWN FOR SPOTTING
TALENT.
NOW L.A. REID SAYS HE'S DONE
WITH JUDGING ON "X FACTOR."
WE'LL TELL YOU WHY.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA AND HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER MEETING FOR
NEARLY AN HOUR YESTERDAY EVENING
IN A FISCAL CLIFF SHOWDOWN, WITH
18 DAYS REMAINING BEFORE WE GO
OVER THE EDGE, BOTH SIDES SAY
THE LINES OF COMMUNICATION
REMAIN OPEN.
MOST OF US HAVE BEEN STRESSING
OVER THE THOUSANDS OF EXTRA
DOLLARS WE MAY HAVE TO FORK OVER
TO UNCLE SAM NEXT YEAR, BUT
ALONG WITH SEQUESTRATION COMES
SWEEPING SPENDING CUTS, TOO, AND
THAT HAS THE DEFENSE DEPARTMENT
UP IN ARMS.
HERE'S PENTAGON CORRESPONDENT
CHRIS LAWRENCE.
>> Reporter: TO HEAR THE
PENTAGON TELL IT --
>> SEQUESTRATION THEREFORE IF IT
WERE ALLOWED TO HAPPEN WOULD
INTRODUCE SENSELESS CHAOS.
>> Reporter: THE FISCAL CLIFF --
>> SEQUESTRATION WILL HAVE A
CHAOTIC EFFECT ON THE FORCE.
>> Reporter: IS AKIN TO
ARMAGEDDON.
>> WHAT I WORRY ABOUT IS BEING
BLIND-SIDED BY A HUGE CUT
BECAUSE THEY DON'T HAVE THE
STRENGTH OR THE COURAGE OR THE
GUTS TO DO WHAT THEY HAVE TO DO.
>> HAPPY HOLIDAYS.
>> Reporter: THE CLIFF WOULD CUT
$500 BILLION IN DEFENSE
SPENDING, BUT SPREAD OUT OVER
THE NEXT TEN YEARS.
WOULD THESE CUTS REALLY BE THAT
BAD?
>> ABSOLUTELY NOT.
>> Reporter: ANALYST BEN FREEMAN
ARGUES THE PENTAGON CAN SURVIVE
ON A SMALLER BUDGET.
>> SEQUESTRATION HAPPENS IT WILL
DROP A LITTLE BIT BUT IT'S
CERTAINLY NOT CATASTROPHIC OR
DOOMSDAY OR ANY OTHER SORT OF
HYPERBOLE THEY WANT TO DESCRIBE
IT AS.
>> Reporter: PERHAPS THE NAVY
WOULD HAVE TO BUY LESS
EXPENSIVE, LESS ADVANCED FIGHTER
JETS INSTEAD OF THE NEW F-35.
OR THE PENTAGON WOULD HAVE TO
CUT THE NUMBER OF SOLDIERS AND
MARINES BACK TO THE LEVELS
BEFORE 9/11.
>> SEQUESTRATION WOULD RISK
HOLLOWING OUT OUR FORCE.
>> Reporter: PENTAGON OFFICIALS
SAY GOING OVER THE CLIFF WOULD
ACTUALLY LEAVE THEM A TRILLION
DOLLARS IN THE HOLE, BECAUSE IT
COMES ON TOP OF CUTS THEY'VE
ALREADY BUDGETED FOR.
>> WE'VE PUT IN PLACE $487
BILLION IN SAVINGS OVER THE NEXT
TEN YEARS.
>> Reporter: ARE THESE "CUTS"
THE SAME SORT OF BUDGET CUTS
THAT YOU AND I THINK OF WHEN WE
THINK OF CUTTING OUR BUDGET?
>> I CALL THEM PHANTOM CUTS
BECAUSE IT'S NOT A REAL SAVINGS.
>> Reporter: FREEMAN SAYS THE
PENTAGON IS COUNTING MONEY IT
WAS PROJECTING TO SPEND AS
SAVINGS WHICH HE SAYS ISN'T THE
SAME AS SIMPLY SPENDING LESS.
>> BUT THIS IS THE WAY D.C. DOES
MATH.
IT'S UNFORTUNATE THAT YOU OR I
CAN'T DO OUR TAXES LIKE THAT BUT
IT'S THE WAY THEY SEEM TO DO
BUSINESS HERE.
>> A SENIOR DEFENSE OFFICIAL
ADMITS THAT EVERYONE AT THE
PENTAGON FROM THE SECRETARY ON
DOWN IS ON AUTOPILOT TO DEFEND
THEIR BUDGET.
EVEN THOUGH HE FEELS THAT THEY
NEED PEOPLE TO GO IN AND
CHALLENGE THEIR COSTS, HE ARGUES
THAT'S BETTER DONE OVER TIME,
NOT FORCED ON THEM BY THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
CHRIS LAWRENCE, CNN, THE
PENTAGON.
>> ALL RIGHT, CHRIS.
>>> ARE YOU WORRIED AIR FARES
MIGHT RISE WITH FEWER AIRLINES
TAKING TO THE SKIES?
WHAT A REPORT FOUND THAT JUST
MIGHT SURPRISE YOU.
I had three kids.
And she became the full time
mother of three.
It was soccer, and ballet, and
cheerleading, and baseball.
Those years were crazy.
So, as we go into
this next phase,
you know, a big part
of it for us is that
there isn't anything on the
schedule.
SOME BIG CHANGES ARE COMING TO
THE "X FACTOR."
RECORD EXECUTIVE L.A. REID
SAYSES HE'S NOT COMING BACK FOR
ANOTHER SEASON.
A.J. HAMMER OF "SHOWBIZ TONIGHT"
IS IN NEW YORK.
>> "THE X FACTOR" HAS HAD A FEW
SHAKEUPS IN THE PAST YEAR.
JUDGE L.A. REID IS LEAVING AFTER
THE SEASON WRAPS UP.
THEY'RE IN THE SECOND SEASON.
THIS WAS CONFIRMED BY A
SPOKESPERSON FOR EPIC RECORDS
WHERE REID IS THE CHAIRMAN AND
CEO.
WE'RE TOLD HE MADE THE DECISION
SO HE COULD CONCENTRATE ON HIS
RESPONSIBILITIES WITH THE RECORD
LABELS.
OBVIOUSLY A PRETTY BIG JOB AND
KEEPS HIM BUSY SO THE LABEL TELD
US REID REALLY NEEDS TO TURN HIS
FULL ATTENTION TO HIS DAY JOB.
NOW THE SHOW HAS SEEN QUITE A
FEW OTHER CHANGES OVER THE PAST
YEAR, SOME TURNOVER WITH BRITNEY
SPEARS AND DEMI LOVATO.
TWO NEW HOSTS, KHLOE KARDASHIAN
ODUM AND REID ENJOYED THE FINAL
BROADCAST AND GOOD NEWS FOR HIM
WINDING THINGS DOWN TO SEE
COUNTRY SINGER TATE STEVENS
BEING VOTED BY FANS INTO NEXT
WEEK'S FINALS SO THE THIRD
SEASON OF "X FACTOR" FIRING UP
WITHOUT L.A. REID AND AT THIS
POINT IT'S ANYONE'S GUESS WHO
WILL REPLACE HIM.
>> IS THE SHOW NOT DOING WELL?
WHAT IS GOING ON?
>> FROM THE BEGINNING IT NEVER
UP WITH SIMON COWELL'S
EXPECTATIONS AND WHAT HE PUT OUT
FOR THE HOPES FOR THE RATINGS
THAT THE SHOW WOULD SEE AND I
THINK L.A. REID, YOU WATCH HIM
ON THE SHOW AND SOMETIMES YOU
WONDER, DOES HE REALLY WANT TO
BE DOING THIS?
HE'S A GREAT JUDGE, I THINK HE
CALLS IT LIKE HE SEES IT BUT HE
HAS A BIG DAY JOB, RUNNING A
RECORD LABEL.
>> IT WAS INTERESTING WHEN THEY
BROUGHT HIM ON, SEEMED LIKE AN
ODD FIT.
>>> HARRY POTTER THE HIGHEST
GROSSING FRANCHISE OF ALL TIME?
>> FOSHDS RELEASED ITS LIST OF
THE HIGHEST GLOBAL BOX OFFICE
FRANCHISES, HARRY POTTER ON TOP,
RANKED NUMBER ONE, EARNINGS OF
$7.7 BILLION, AS YOU SEE IT'S
FOLLOWED BY "STAR WARS" $4.5
BILLION, THE THIRD IS THE JAMES
BOND FILMS ALSO THE LONGEST
LASTING AND IN THE SPAN OF 50
YEARS THEY'VE DONE 24 FILMS
STARING SEVEN DASHING ACTION
HEROES FOLLOWED BY "PIRATES OF
THE CARIBBEAN" AND "BATMAN" IN
FIFTH PLACE.
EVEN THOUGH "HARRY POTTER" IS
THE HIGHEST GROSSING FRANCHISE,
"LORD OF THE RINGS" IS A SERIOUS
CONTENDER.
NEW FILMS ON THE WAY.
THE FRANCHISE RANKS NINTH,
EARNINGS OF ALMOST $3 BILLION
BUT "THE HOBBIT" THREE-PART
SERIES WHICH HITS THEATERS TODAY
HAS THE POTENTIAL TO MAKE "LORLD
OF THE RINGS" ONE OF THE MOST
LUCRATIVE FRANCHISES OF ALL-TIME
AND I CERTAINLY KNOW THEY'RE
GOING TO DO HUGE BOX OFFICE, IT
WILL BE AN EASY WIN FOR NUMBER
ONE THIS WEEKEND, DON.
>> GOODNESS GRACIOUS, WE ARE IN
THE WRONG BUSINESS.
MY GOODNESS.
THANK YOU, A.J.
>>> NEXT HOUR, A.J. HAS THE
STORY OF A MAN CAUGHT TRYING TO
BREAK INTO TAYLOR SWIFT'S HOME
AND HE WAS ARMED WITH A KNIFE.
CHECKING OUR TOP STORIES RIGHT
NOW THE DEEJAYS WHO PRANKED THE
HOSPITAL WHERE PRINCE WILLIAM'S
PREGNANT WIFE WAS STAYING SAYING
THEY ARE NOT GETTING DEATH
THREATS SO THE DEEJAYS AND TEN
STATION EXECUTIVES HAVE HIRED
BODYGUARDS AND SOME REPORTS SAY
THE DEEJAYS HAVE BEEN MOVED TO A
SAFEHOUSE.
THE NURSE WHO ANDED THE PRANK
CALL COMMITTED SUICIDE LAST
WEEK.
>>> A U.S. VETERAN SAYS HE'S
BEEN PUT ON THE FBI'S NO FLY
LIST AND DOESN'T KNOW WHY.
HE HELD A PRESS CONFERENCE IN
OKLAHOMA CITY, THEY SAID THE FBI
AND LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS
FOLLOWED AND HARASSED LONG AND
HIS SISTER.
IN A STATEMENT THE FBI SAYS IT
DOES NOT VIOLATE ANYONE'S CIVIL
RIGHTS.
>>> LOUISIANA GOVERNOR BOBBY
JINDAL SAYS BIRTH CONTROL SHOULD
BE SOLD OVER THE COUNTER.
IN A "WALL STREET JOURNAL" OP-ED
HE WRITES THE POLITICAL BATTLE
OVER HEALTH INSURANCE COVERAGE
FOR CONTRACEPTION WOULDN'T BE
REPEATED IF WOMEN COULD BUY IT
WITHOUT A PRESCRIPTION AS AND A
CONSERVATIVE REPUBLICAN I
BELIEVE THAT WE HAVE BEEN STUPID
TO LET THE DEMOCRATS DEMAGOGUE
THE CONTRACEPTIVES ISSUE AND
PRETEND, DURING DEBATES ABOUT
HEALTH CARE INSURANCE, THAT
REPUBLICANS ARE SOMEHOW AGAINST
BIRTH CONTROL."
>>> THE TWINKIE AND OTHER
HOSTESS BRAND TREATS COULD BE
BACK IN YOUR LUNCH BAG, THEY'RE
HOPING.
BLOOMBERG NEWS REPORTS WALMART
AND KROGER ARE AMONG THE BIDDERS
FOR THE ICONIC BRAND.
HOSTESS BEGAN TO WIND DOWN ITS
OPERATION LAST MONTH AFTER
FAILING TO RESOLVE A CONTRACT
DISPUTE WITH ITS BAKERS UNION.
HOSTESS WILL AUCTION BRANDS LIKE
TWINKIES AND CUPCAKES EARLY NEXT
YEAR.
>>> A NEW REPORT SAYS JUST
BECAUSE THERE ARE FEWER
AIRLINES, THAT DOESN'T MEAN AIR
FARES HAVE GONE SKY HIGH.
MABIBEL ABER IS AT THE NASDAQ
MARKETSITE FOLLOWING THIS STORY.
MARIBEL WHAT DID THE REPORT
FIND?
>> IT MAY FEEL LIKE YOU'RE
PAYING MORE BUT IT'S FROM
PRICEWATER HOUSE COOPERS.
THERE HAVE BEEN A LOT OF
MERGERS.
DELTA AND NORTHWEST, CONTINENTAL
AND UNITED, SOUTHWEST AND
AIRTRAN.
WHENEVER WE'VE HEARD ABOUT AN
AIRLINE MERGER, PEOPLE THINK
LESS COMPETITION AND HIGHER
PRICES.
"USA TODAY" SAYS THE DRAMATIC
PRICE INCREASES THAT SOME PEOPLE
EXPECTED THEY JUST HAVEN'T
HAPPENED AND NOW YES PRICES ARE
HIGHER.
THE THING IS NOT THAT MUCH.
DOMESTIC TICKET PRICES HAVE BEEN
RISING ONLY 1.8% A YEAR SO
THAT'S LESS THAN THE RATE OF
INFLATION.
ALSO WANT TO POINT OUT WHEN A
CARRIER MOVES OUT OF THE MARKET
ANOTHER ONE USUALLY MOVES IN,
AND SO THAT'S MAINTAINING THE
COMPETITION.
DON?
>> ALL RIGHT, THANK YOU,
MARIBEL.
>>> THE ANGELS MAKE JOSH
HAMILTON THE $125 MILLION MAN.
CAN THE HUGE OFFSEASON SIGNING
LEAD TO POST SEASON SUCCESS?
WE'LL TALK ABOUT IT.
ANNCR: Some politicians seem to
think Medicare and...
Social Security are just numbers
in a budget.
Well, we worked hard for those
benefits.
We earned them.
And if Washington tries to cram
decisions about the future...
of these programs into a last
minute budget deal...
we'll all pay the price.
AARP is fighting to protect
seniors with responsible...
solutions that strengthen
Medicare and...
Social Security for generations
to come.
We can do better than a last
minute deal...
that would hurt all of us.
.
>>> NEW YORK KNICKS FANS HAVE
SOMETHING TO CHEER FOR A CHANGE.
THE KNICKS ARE LIVING IN THE
PENTHOUSE OF THE NBC'S EASTERN
CONFERENCE AND LAST NIGHT WON A
STATE GAME.
VINCE JOINS ME NOW.
HELLO, SIR.
NBA HOOPS ARE HOT AGAIN IN NEW
YORK.
WHAT'S UP WITH THAT?
>> THAT'S A GOOD THING, I TELL
YOU.
IT'S GOOD FOR THE ENTIRE LEAGUE.
WHEN THE KNICKS ARE PLAYING
WELL, THE NBA IS VERY, VERY
HAPPY.
THURSDAY NIGHT IT WAS THE KNICKS
TAKING ON THE VISITING LOS
ANGELES LAKERS.
THE INTERESTING POINT WAS, THE
LAKER COACH COMING BACK, THE
COACH AGAINST THE TEAM THAT HE
WALKED AWAY FROM IN MARCH.
THE LAKERS ARE STRUGGLING AND
DID LAST NIGHT.
THE MVP CANDIDATE, CARMELO
ANTHONY, SPRAINED HIS KNEE.
KOBE BRYANT IS BEYOND FRUSTRATED
WITH HIS TEAM.
>> EVERY GAME FOR US HAS A LOT
OF MEANING TO IT AT THIS POINT.
I DON'T THINK -- MAYBE IF WE
WERE ROLLING, PLAYING WELL IT
PROBABLY HAS ADDED SIGNIFICANCE.
BUT AT THIS POINT, YOU KNOW, I
WISH WE HAD THE WASHINGTON
GENERALS ON OUR SCHEDULE.
>> IT'S NOT GOING TO BE
WASHINGTON GENERALS BUT RATHER
THE WASHINGTON WIZARDS.
PICK UP TICKETS.
THEY ARE THERE IN TOWN.
YOU CAN WATCH THEM.
>> CAN WE TALK ABOUT THIS HUGE
SIGNING IN BASEBALL, JOSH
HAMILTON, $25 MILLION A YEAR?
>> YEAH.
I THINK YOU'RE WORTH WHAT
SOMEONE IS WILLING TO PAY.
JOSH HAS BEEN A TREMENDOUS POWER
HITTER FOR A NUMBER OF YEARS.
FIVE YEARS, $125 MILLION.
HE'S HEADED TO A DIVISION RIVAL.
THAT MAKES IT EVEN MORE
INTERESTING.
THE DODGERS HAVE BEEN DOING A
LOT OF THE FREE AGENT SIGNING.
IT'S THE ANGELS GETTING HAMILTON
TO SIGN A POWERFUL LINEUP.
THE ANGELS MAKING NOISE IN TOWN
AND THEY ARE ALSO NOW HEATING UP
A DIVISION RIVALRY WITH THE
TEXAS RANGERS.
MEANWHILE, FORMER ANGEL, NOW
DETROIT TIGER TORII HUNTER SAID
THIS, I WAS TOLD MONEY WAS TIGHT
BUT I GUESS THE ARTE HAD MONEY
HIDDEN UNDER A MATTRESS.
BUSINESS IS BUSINESS.
BUT DON'T LIE.
>> SOMEONE IS ALL UPSET WHEN
SOMEONE ELSE GETS BIG MONEY.
>> WHAT DO WE SAY?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THE SPECIFICS
ARE BUT DON'T HATE THE PLAYER.
HATE THE GAME.
IT IS SPORTS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SPOKE ABOUT THE
NHL LOCKOUT YESTERDAY.
LISTEN TO THIS.
>> THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES SHOULDN'T HAVE TO GET
INVOLVED IN A SPORT LOCKOUT.
MY MESSAGE IS, YOU GUYS MAKE A
LOT OF MONEY AND YOU MAKE A LOT
OF MONEY ON THE BACK OF FANS.
SO DO RIGHT BY YOUR FANS.
>> SO THEY'VE MISSED ABOUT HALF
A SEASON NOW.
CAN THAT HELP, THE PRESIDENT'S
COMMENTS?
>> YOU KNOW, I WISH IT COULD
HELP.
BOTH MANAGEMENT AND PLAYERS
UNDERSTAND WHAT IT AT STAKE
HERE.
I DON'T KNOW IF IT'S GOING TO
MOVE THINGS ALONG.
90 DAYS NOW THEY HAVE HAD THE
WORK STOPPAGE AND THE NHL IS THE
ONLY LEAGUE TO LOCKOUT PLAYERS
FOR AN ENTIRE SEASON.
>> THAT'S GOING TO DO IT.
GO TO BLEACHERREPORT.COM
INCLUDING A BIZARRE STORY
BETWEEN A TELEVISION REPORTER
AND NEWSPAPER STORY QUESTIONING
ROBERT GRIFFIN III'S BLACKNESS.
G
>> I HEARD THAT ON THE RADIO.
I'M LIKE, REALLY?
WELL, IT IS SPORTS, AS WE SAY.
THANK YOU.
>> DON, THANK YOU.
HAVE A GREAT WEEKEND.
>> YOU, TOO.
♪
>> IT MAY BE SOME OF THE MOST
PRECIOUS SILENCE EVER CAPTURED
IN A RECORDING STUDIO.
WE'LL TELL YOU ABOUT STEVIE
WONDER'S SURPRISE APPEARANCE.
I'm gonna stand
up to her!
No you're not.
I know.
You know Ronny folks who save
hundreds of dollars
switching to GEICO
sure are happy.
How happy are they Jimmy?
Happier than a witch in
a broom factory.
Get happy. Get GEICO.
Fifteen minutes could save you
fifteen percent or more.
SINCE AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL
WAS FOUNDED BACK IN 1894,
THEY'VE BEEN COMMITTED
TO PUTTING CLIENTS FIRST.
HELPING GENERATIONS
THROUGH TOUGH TIMES.
GOOD TIMES.
NEVER TAKING A BAILOUT.
THERE WHEN YOU NEED THEM.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
OVER THE CENTURIES.
THE STRENGTH OF
A GLOBAL FINANCIAL LEADER.
THE HEART OF
A ONE-TO-ONE RELATIONSHIP.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
TO THE BEST VACATION
SP(ALL) THE GULF!
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHICH OF
OUR GREAT STATES FOLKS VISIT.
MISSISSIPPI,
ALABAMA,
LOUISIANA
OR FLORIDA,
THEY'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
SHAUL, YOUR ALABAMA
HOSPITALITY IS INCREDIBLE.
THANKS, KAREN.
LOVE YOUR MISSISSIPPI OUTDOORS.
I VOTE FOR YOUR
FLORIDA BEACHES, DAWN.
BILL, THIS LOUISIANA
SEAFOOD IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR ON THE GULF,
WE'VE DECIDED TO PUT
ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
NOW IS THE PERFECT TIME TO
VISIT ANYONE OF OUR STATES.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE, GO FISHING
OR JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
WE'VE GOT COASTLINE TO EXPLORE
AND WILDLIFE TO PHOTOGRAPH.
AND THERE'S WORLD CLASS DINING
WITH OUR WORLD FAMOUS SEAFOOD.
SO FOR A GREAT VACATION
THIS YEAR, COME TO THE GULF.
ITS ALL FABULOUS BUT
I GIVE FLORIDA THE EDGE.
RIGHT AFTER MISSISSIPPI.
YOU MEAN ALABAMA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
THIS INVITATION IS
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP
AND ALL OF US WHO
CALL THE GULF HOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
BORN FROM THE ELEMENTS.
♪
DESTINED TO TAKE THEM OVER.
THE UCONNECT COMMAND CENTER
WITH SIRIUS XM SATELLITE RADIO
IN THE NEW 2013 RAM 1500.
ENGINEERED TO MOVE HEAVEN
AND EARTH.
GUTS. GLORY.
RAM.
>>> AN ASPIRING TEEN ARTIST MAY
HAVE GOTTEN THE SURPRISE OF HIS
LIFE.
HERE'S JEAN YNE MOOS.
>> Reporter: HE'S A 14-YEAR-OLD
UP AND COMER SINGER AND WHEN HIS
RECORD MANAGEMENT TOLD HIM TO
COME TO L.A. AND RECORD A STEVIE
WONDER SONG, HE DIDN'T WONDER.
HE JUST DID IT AND WALKED WITH
HIS EYES CLOSED RIGHT INTO THE
MOTHER OF ALL PRANKS OF HAVING
YOUR IDOL SUDDENLY MATERIALIZE
AS YOU'RE SINGING A SONG CAN BE
CALLED A PRANK.
♪
>> SON, HOW YOU DOING?
>> PINCH ME.
PINCH ME.
>> PINCH YOU?
>> CAN I HAVE A HUG?
>> WHAT'S UP, MAN?
>> OH!
>> Reporter: EVEN AFTER THE HUG,
IT DOESN'T HURT TO DOUBLE-CHECK.
>> STEVIE WONDER?
>> Reporter: I WAS WAITING FOR
YOU TO ASK FOR HIS LICENSE IT
TURNS OUT THEY BEGGED STEVIE
WONDER'S MANAGER TO LISTEN TO
HIS VIDEOS.
AFTER LISTENING, HE HE AGREED TO
SHOW UP AND SURPRISE THE KID.
>> THAT WAS JUST BLIND BLOWING.
>> Reporter: AND THEN STEVIE
PLAYED WHILE ASSAN SANG.
IT TURNS OUT THIS WASN'T THE
FIRST TIME THAT STEVIE WONDER
HAS DONE THIS.
OPRAH CALLS IT ONE OF HER
FAVORITE MOMENTS, STAR SEARCH
CHAMPION SINGING STEVIE WONDER'S
"ISN'T SHE WONDERFUL."
♪
>> OH, MY GOSH!
>> Reporter: EVENTUALLY THEY
TURNED IT INTO A DUET.
THE PRANK ON ASSAN WAS AN
ATTEMPT BY HIS RECORD COMPANY TO
CREATE A VIRAL VIDEO BUT HIS MOM
CRIED AND SO DID ASSAN.
♪
>> Reporter: TO THEM THE
SURPRISE WAS NOTHING LESS THAN
STEVIE WONDERFUL.
CNN, JEANNE MOOS, NEW YORK.
>> HE'S RIGHT.
THAT WAS AWESOME.
>>> AND THE NEXT HOUR OF THE CNN
"NEWSROOM" BEGINS RIGHT NOW.
AND HAPPENING IN THE NEWSROOM, A
CRUMBLING REGIME AND A THREAT OF
CHEMICAL WEAPONS AS THE U.S.
RUSHES TO PROTECT AN ALLY THAT
SHARES A BORDER WITH SYRIA.
>>> SUSAN RICE WITHDRAWS HER
NAME TO REPLACE HILLARY CLINTON.
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S SHORT LIST
JUST GOT A LOT SHORTER.
>>> WE'VE GOT BIGGER FISH TO
FRY.
THAT'S WHAT HE PRESIDENT OBAMA
TOLD BARBARA WALTERS ABOUT GOING
AFTER RECREATION FLAT POT
SMOKERS IN COLORADO AND
WASHINGTON WHERE IT'S LEGAL.
>>> A LOT OF AMERICANS BELIEVE
THE MAYANS MAY BE RIGHT.
CNN "NEWSROOM" STARTS RIGHT NOW.
>>> GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE, FROM
WASHINGTON I'M DON LEMON IN THE
PLACE WHERE THE BIGGEST STORY IS
HAPPENING THIS HOUR.
SUSAN RICE DROPS OUT OF THE
RUNNING FOR SECRETARY OF STATE.
THE JOB SEEMED TO BE HERS.
BUT THEN THERE WAS A DEADLY
ATTACK ON THE CONSULATE IN
LIBYA.
DAYS LATER, U.S. AMBASSADOR
CHRIS STEVENS AND THREE OTHER
AMERICANS WERE KILLED.
RICE SAID IT WAS A SPONTANEOUS
ATTACK THAT GOT OUT OF HAND
RATHER THAN A PLANNED ATTACK.
RICE DEFENDS HER HANDLING EVEN
NOW.
>> I WAS VERY CAREFUL TO EXPLAIN
THAT THE INFORMATION WAS
PRELIMINARY AND IT COULD CHANGE
AND YET I THINK IT WAS
MISCONSTRUED AND CON TORTED INTO
SOMETHING MORE NEFARIOUS THAT
WAS NEVER INDEED THE CASE NOR MY
INTENTION.
>> WELL, THE BACKLASH AGAINST
RICE ONLY GREW AFTER SHE MET
WITH CONCERNED LAWMAKERS BEHIND
CLOSED DOORS.
THE ODDS OF A CONFIRMATION HAD
GROWN SO BLEAK THE WHITE HOUSE
NEVER WENT THROUGH A FORMAL
NOMINATION.
>> I HADN'T MADE A DECISION
ABOUT WHO WOULD BE MY NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE.
THERE'S NO DOUBT THAT SUSAN WAS
QUALIFIED.
THERE ARE OTHER PEOPLE WHO ARE
QUALIFIED AS WELL.
HER INTEREST IS MORE IN IS
SERVING THE COUNTRY THAN ME.
SHE WILL CONTINUE TO BE ONE OF
MY TOP MEMBERS OF THE NATIONAL
SECURITY TEAM.
>> SO WHO IS ON THE LIST TO
REPLACE SECRETARY OF STATE
HILLARY CLINTON?
JILL DOUGHERTY IS JOINING US.
HI, JILL.
>> HI, DON.
OF COURSE THAT NAME IS JOHN
KERRY, A HEAVYWEIGHT IN FOREIGN
POLICY AND MAYBE IT'S FUNNY THAT
HE LOOKS LIKE A SECRETARY OF
STATE WITH THAT GRAY HAIR, VERY
TALL, DISTINGUISHED BUT MORE
SERIOUSLY, HE DOES KNOW THE
ISSUES.
HE'S BEEN INVOLVED IN THESE
ISSUES -- WORLD ISSUES FOR A
LONG TIME.
HE'S KIND OF A SURROGATE FOR THE
ADMINISTRATION, INCLUDING BEING
KIND OF AN UNOFFICIAL ENVOY ON
AFGHANISTAN AND PAKISTAN.
AND THE TIES TO MR. OBAMA GO WAY
BACK.
YOU COULD SAY GO BACK TO THE
2004 ELECTION WHEN SENATOR KERRY
TOOK BARACK OBAMA ON THE MAP BY
GIVING HIM A CHANCE TO SPEAK AT
THE CONVENTION.
SO THAT'S ONE FACTOR.
I THINK YOU WOULD SAY THAT HE'S
A VERY LIKELY CANDIDATE NOBODY
THINKS THAT HE'LL HAVE ANY
TROUBLE SAILING THROUGH IN THE
SENATE.
>> AND AFTER ALL, JOHN McCAIN
DID SAY -- DID CALL HIM AND
JOKINGLY HE SAID, MR. SECRETARY,
WHEN THEY WERE IN THE MIDDLE OF
A CONFERENCE RECENTLY.
SO CHANS ARE THAT HE MAY -- HE
MAY GO THROUGH WITHOUT ANY
PROBLEM.
>> YES.
ALTHOUGH, IRONICALLY, REMEMBER
BACK IN 2004 WHEN HE WAS, QUOTE,
SWIFT-BOATED BY REPUBLICANS
CRITICIZING HIM FOR HIS MILITARY
FACTOR.
NOW IT'S PRETTY MUCH A LOVE FEST
AND HE LOOKS LIKE HE REALLY
WOULD BE THE CANDIDATE.
NO QUESTION.
>> JILL, YOU KNOW THIS.
WASHINGTON IS LIKE THE WEATHER.
IF YOU DON'T LIKE IT, STICK
AROUND.
IT WILL CHANGE.
YOU'RE RIGHT ABOUT THAT.
JILL DOUGHERTY, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
>>> 18 DAYS TO GO AND STILL NO
DEAL AND NOW THE DEBT CEILING IS
IN THE MIX HERE.
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER SAYS
NO WAY.
>> DO YOU THINK THAT SENATOR
REID OR THEN SENATOR OBAMA WOULD
HAVE EVER GIVEN TO PRESIDENT
GEORGE W. BUSH THE UNLIMITED
ABILITY TO RAISE THE DEBT LIMIT?
I KNOW THEY ARE TALKING ABOUT
DOING OH IT NOW.
DO YOU THINK THERE'S ANY CHANCE
THAT THEN SENATOR REID OR OBAMA
WOULD HAVE DONE THAT?
NEVER.
CONGRESS IS NEVER GOING TO GIVE
UP OUR ABILITY TO CONTROL THE
PURSE.
>> MEANWHILE, PRESIDENT OBAMA IS
HOLDING FIRM ON HIS PLANS TO
KEEP MIDDLE CLASS TAX RATES
STEADY.
>> THE MOST IMPORTANT THING WE
CAN DO RIGHT NOW IS MAKE SURE
THAT MIDDLE CLASS TAXES DON'T GO
UP.
IT'S THE BEST THING FOR THE
ECONOMY, AMERICAN FAMILIES, AND
IF WE DO THAT, SENATE HAS
ALREADY PASSED THIS BILL.
HOUSE DEMOCRATS ARE READY TO
PASS IT.
THE ONLY HOLDOUT ARE THE HOUSE
REPUBLICANS.
IF WE GET THAT DONE, THAT WILL
TAKE THE EDGE OFF THINGS.
WE'LL HAVE TO DEAL WITH DEFICIT
PROBLEMS BUT 98% OF AMERICANS,
97% OF SMALL BUSINESSES WILL NOT
SEE THEIR TAXES GO UP.
WE SHOULD GET THAT DONE.
>> WELL, THE HOUSE IS SCHEDULED
TO GO HOME FOR THE YEAR TODAY
BUT HOUSE MAJORITY LEADER ERIC
CANTOR SAID MEMBERS COULD KEEP
ON WORKING WITH THE FISCAL CLIFF
STILL UNRESOLVED.
>>> NOW A DESPERATE REGIME
HOLDING ON TO POWER.
WASHINGTON IS DEPLOYING TWO
PATRIOT MISSILES TO OUR ALLY,
TURKEY.
THE ARSENAL OF SCUD MISSILES AND
POSSIBLE CHEMICAL WEAPONS.
>> THIS IS A CHALLENGING TIME.
IT'S A CHALLENGING TIME.
IT'S A CRITICAL TIME.
WE JUST ANNOUNCED THIS MORNING
THAT WE ARE DEPLOYING TWO
PATRIOT TO TURKEY ALONG WITH THE
TROOPS NECESSARY TO MAN THOSE
BATTERIES SO WE CAN HELP TURKEY
HAVE THE KIND OF MISSILE DEFENSE
IT MAY VERY WELL NEED IN DEALING
WITH THREATS THAT COME OUT OF
SYRIA.
>> LET'S GO TO BEIRUT NOW.
NICK PATON WALSH IS FOLLOWING
THE LATEST DEVELOPMENTS FOR US.
NICK, WHAT DO YOU KNOW?
>> Reporter: WE DON'T EXACTLY
KNOW WHERE THESE TROOPS ARE
GOING TO BE PLACED ON THE
TURKISH SIDE OF THE BORDER BUT
IT'S PRITLY LIKELY THEY WILL BE
PLACED WITHIN THE NEXT FEW WEEKS
INTO EARLY NEXT YEAR.
WE KNOW THAT GERMANY AND NET
THEY ARE NETHERLANDS ARE ONSET
TO DEPLOY THEIR TROOPS AS WELL.
THIS IS AN INCREDIBLE VOLATILE
AREA.
REMEMBER, THIS ALL STARTED
BECAUSE TWO MONTHS AGO THERE
WERE EXCHANGES OF FIRE BETWEEN
THE TURKISH AND SYRIAN FIRE
OFTEN BY SYRIAN MILITARY.
THEY ASKED FOR HELP FROM NATO
AND NOW THEY GOT WHAT THEY ASKED
FOR.
WE'RE HEARING FROM SECRETARY OF
DEFENSE LEON PANETTA THAT THERE
IS A PLAN FOR THE YOUU.S. TO GE
INVOLVED IF CHEMICAL WEAPONS ARE
USED.
IT'S NOT CLEAR IF THE PATRIOTS
WILL BE INVOLVED IN THAT.
THEY ARE DESIGNED TO TAKE OUT
MISSILES.
WE'RE SEEING AN HE ESCALATION N
AND CONTRIBUTING MILITARY MEANS
TO THE AREA.
CERTAINLY TENSIONS ARE EVEN
HIGHER ON THAT BORDER.
DON?
>> NICK PATON WALSH, THANK YOU.
>>> PRESIDENT BARACK OBAMA
SPEAKING OUT ABOUT RECREATIONAL
MARIJUANA USE.
IN AN INTERVIEW WITH BARBARA
WALTERS, THE PRESIDENT SAID THE
U.S. GOVERNMENT HAS, QUOTE,
BIGGER FISH TO FRY THAN GOING
AFTER USERS.
>> YOU KNOW, THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT HAS A LOT TO DO WHEN
IT COMES TO CRIMINAL
PROSECUTIONS.
IT DOES NOT MAKE SENSE FROM A
PRIORITIZATION POINT OF VIEW FOR
US TO FOCUS ON RECREATIONAL DRUG
USERS IN A STATE THAT HAS
ALREADY SAID THAT UNDER STATE
LAW THAT'S LEGAL.
>> THIS IS THE FIRST TIME THE
PRESIDENT HAS SPOKEN ON THE
ISSUE SINCE COLORADO AND
WASHINGTON LEGALIZED
RECREATIONAL USE OF MARIJUANA.
>>> THE U.S. GEOLOGICAL SERVICE
SAYS A PAIR OF EARTHQUAKES
MEASURING 6.4 AND 6.1 IN
MAGNITUDE STRUCK OFF BAJA,
CALIFORNIA, EARLIER THIS
MORNING.
THEY WERE FOLLOWED BY SMALLER
AFTERSHOCKS.
NO TSUNAMI WARNING HAS BEEN
ISSUED AND NO DAMAGE REPORTED.
>>> IF YOU'RE FLYING ANYWHERE
FOR THE HOLIDAY, YOU BETTER HOPE
YOU GOT YOUR CHRISTMAS BONUS
EARLY.
FARES ARE UP TO AN AVERAGE OF
$414 FOR A ROUND TRIP TICKET.
YES, IT'S TRUE.
THEY ARE EXPENSIVE LATELY.
THAT'S UP 9% FROM LAST YEAR.
>>> A MARINE IS DENIED THE
PRESTIGIOUS MEDAL OF HONOR AFTER
HE PAID THE ULTIMATE PRICE,
FIGHTING FOR HIS COUNTRY.
WE'LL HAVE HIS STORY NEXT.
JILL D
A GREAT LIFE.
BUT SHE HAS SOME DENTAL ISSUES
SHE'S NOT HAPPY ABOUT.
SO I INTRODUCED JILL
TO CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SELECTED FOR PEOPLE OVER 50.
PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE IS A
TOOTHPASTE THAT DEFENDS AGAINST
TENDER, INFLAMED GUMS,
SENSITIVITY AND WEAK ENAMEL.
CONDITIONS PEOPLE OVER 50
EXPERIENCE.
CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SO JILL CAN KEEP LIVING
THE GOOD LIFE.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
LOOK THIS ISN'T
MY FIRST CHRISTMAS.
THESE DEALS ALL SEEM GREAT
AT THE TIME...
BUT LATER...
[ shirt ]
MERRY CHRISTMAS, EVERYBODY!
NOT SO MUCH.
HO HO HO!
THIS ISN'T
THAT KIND OF DEAL.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SAVE ON GROUND SHIPPING
AT FEDEX OFFICE.
♪ HARK HOW THE BELLS,
SWEET SILVER BELLS ♪
♪ ALL SEEM TO SAY
THROW CARE AWAY ♪
♪ FROM EVERYWHERE,
FILLING THE AIR ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
CHEX PARTY MIX.
EASY 15-MINUTE
HOMEMADE RECIPES
YOU JUST POP IN A MICROWAVE.
LIKE CARAMEL CHOCOLATE
DRIZZLES.
HAPPIER HOLIDAYS.
CHEX PARTY MIX.
Meet the 5-passenger
Ford C-MAX Hybrid.
When you're carrying
a lot of weight,
C-MAX has a nice little trait,
You see, C-MAX helps
you load your freight,
with its foot-activated
lift gate.
But that's not
all you'll see,
Cause C-MAX also
beats Prius v,
with better MPG.
Say hi to the all-new 47
combined MPG C-MAX Hybrid.
STORIES.
THERE COULD BE A KEY DEAL NEXT
MONTH WHICH WOULD ALLOW
INSPECTORS ACCESS TO A MILITARY
SITE WHERE THE WEST IS
SUSPECTING NUCLEAR MATERIALS.
>>> NORTH KOREA CELEBRATES A
ROCKET LAUNCH THAT PUT A
SATELLITE INTO ORBIT.
CROWDS WERE SHOWN CLAPPING AND
CHEERING AS OFFICIALS MADE
CONGRATULATORY SPEECHES.
THE SUCCESS FOR THE MISSION IS
UP FOR DEBATE.
THE U.S. BELIEVES THAT NORTH
KOREA MAY NOT HAVE FULL CONTROL
OF THE SATELLITE.
>>> DO YOU KNOW THIS MAN?
TAKE A LOOK.
IF SO, YOUR INFORMATION COULD BE
WORTH $5,000.
THE FBI IS HOPING THE REWARD
WILL LEAD TO THE ARREST OF A
ROBBER WHO HAS HIT 13 BANKS FROM
VIRGINIA ALL THE WAY TO
CALIFORNIA.
HE IS BEING CALLED THE RAY
BANDIT BECAUSE OF HIS
SUNGLASSES.
>>> A MALL IN OREGON WHERE THE
SHOOTING RAMPAGE OCCURRED WILL
REOPEN IN A FEW HOURS.
SEVERAL MALL WORKERS SAY THEY
ARE HESITANT ABOUT RETURNING TO
THE MALL.
>>> AN UPDATE TO CONTROVERSIAL
STORY THAT WE TOLD YOU ABOUT
YESTERDAY.
A MARINE WHO DIED WHILE FIGHTING
IN IRAQ.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT A SERGEANT
AND MARINES AND FELLOW SOLDIERS
SAY THAT HE DESERVES THE MEDAL.
>> ONE OF THE INSURGENTS THREW A
GRENADE INTO WHERE HE WAS LYING
AND THAT'S WHEN HE PULLED IT
UNDER HIMSELF AND SAVED PRETTY
MUCH EVERYONE IN THE ROOM,
MYSELF AND OTHER MARINES IN THE
HOUSE ALL OWE HIM OUR LIVES.
>> BUT SECRETARY LEON PANETTA
SAYS THERE'S TOO MUCH
CONFLICTING EVIDENCE.
IT INDICATES THAT HE MAY HAVE
BEEN BRAIN DEAD BEFORE HE FELL
ON THE GRENADE.
OTHER EVIDENCE IS THAT THE
GRENADE DIDN'T EVEN EXPLODE
UNDERNEATH HIM.
JOINING ME NOW IS GEORGE, A
REPRESENTATIVE FOR THE FAMILY.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR
HAVING ME ON.
>> LET ME READ A RESPONSE TO YOU
FROM SECRETARY PANETTA.
IN LIGHT OF THE STRICT STANDARDS
THAT HAVE BEEN ESTABLISHED FOR
AWARDING THE MEDAL OF HONOR, I
CANNOT IN GOOD CONSCIENCE CHANGE
THE RECOMMENDATION OF SECRETARY
ROBERT GATES.
HOW DOES THE FAMILY FEEL ABOUT
THIS?
>> THE FAMILY IS VERY UPSET
BECAUSE THE FAMILY BELIEVES THE
MARINES THAT WERE THERE, THE
ONES THAT WERE ACTUALLY INSIDE
THE HOUSE ON THAT DAY, NOVEMBER
15th, 2004.
AND FORENSIC EVIDENCE AND SECOND
GUESSING WILL NEVER CHANGE THEIR
VIEWS ON WHAT HAPPENED THAT DAY.
>> THIS IS A SECOND TIME THAT
PERALTA HAS BEEN DENIED THE
MEDAL OF HONOR.
>> WE MARINES BELIEVE IN HONOR.
AS LONG AS THERE IS A MARINE
CORPS, THERE WILL BE A MARINE
FIGHTING FOR SERGEANT PERALTA
AND RIGHT NOW A FORMER MARINE IS
THE ONE LEADING THE FIGHT FOR
HIM.
>> DO YOU THINK IT'S IMPORTANT
THAT THE DEFENSE DEPARTMENT IS
TRYING TO UPHOLD A STANDARD FOR
THE MEDAL OF HONOR?
>> THE DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE
ALWAYS SAYS THAT THE STANDARD
HAS NEVER CHANGED.
THEY ARE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT ABOUT
THAT.
BUT WHAT HAS CHANGED IS THE
PROCEDURES TO GET TO THAT
STANDARD.
IN WORLD WAR II IT TOOK MONTHS.
TODAY IT TAKES YEARS TO AWARD A
MEDAL OF HONOR.
>> FOUR OF THE WITNESSES
APPARENTLY GIVE A MOSTLY
CONSISTENT ACCOUNT OF WHAT
HAPPENED.
SO WHY DO YOU THINK A MEDICAL
EXAMINER'S REPORT IS GIVEN SO
MUCH WEIGHT?
>> THE MEDAL EXAMINER, WHEN HE
GAVE THAT REPORT, HE DIDN'T HAVE
THE BENEFIT OF SERGEANT
PERALTA'S BODY.
HE GAVE A REPORT BASED ON COMBAT
INFORMATION.
DURING THAT BATTLE OF FALLUJA,
THE BATTLE WAS STILL GOING ON.
HE RENDERED AN OPINION WITH
INCOMPLETE INFORMATION AND
THAT'S WHY WE BELIEVE THAT THE
VIDEO THAT WAS SHOT THAT DAY IS
COMPELLING EVIDENCE THAT
SERGEANT PERALTA RATES MEDAL.
>> AS YOU KNOW, HE WAS HONORED
WITH A NAVY CROSS.
NOT ENOUGH THOUGH, YOU BELIEVE?
>> THE NAVY CROSS, IF HE DOESN'T
RATE THE MEDAL OF HONOR, IN
REALITY, SERGEANT PERALTA DOES
NOT DESERVE THE NAVY CROSS.
HOWEVER, TO CIVILIANS AND THE
DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE DID NOT
APPROVE A MEDAL OF HONOR.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR YOUR
TIME, SIR.
WE APPRECIATE YOU JOINING US.
>> THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
>> YEAH, THANK YOU.
>>> IN OTHER NEWS NOW, FLOODS,
FIRE, AND A MASSIVE DROUGHT.
THE EFFECTS OF CLIMATE CHANGE OR
SOMETHING MORE.
IS IT MORE SIGNIFICANT?
WHY SOME SAY THIS YEAR'S WILD
WEATHER COULD HAVE BIBLICAL
IMPLICATIONS.
♪
[ Woman ]
♪ WHAT I WANT THIS SEASON
♪ IF YOU'D LIKE
TO TRY AND GUESS ♪
♪ IT IS SOMETHING VERY SPECIAL
♪ I WOULD READILY CONFESS
[ dogs barking ]
♪ 'CAUSE ALL I WANT
THIS SEASON ♪
♪ IS SOMETHING FROM YOUR HEART
♪ LA DA DA, LA DA DA
[ Male Announcer ] THINKING
OF OTHERS THIS HOLIDAY SEASON,
TRAVELERS.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
>>> OH, MY GOD.
>> OKAY.
THAT WAS THE CLASSIC FILM
"2012."
IT'S FULL OF DEATH-DEFYING
ESCAPES AND THE EARTH
DISAPPEARING LITERALLY BENEATH
THE ACTORS' FEET.
IT'S HOLLYWOOD'S TAKE ON THE
APOCOLYPSE BUT SOME SAY THE END
OF DAYS MAY BE LESS ABOUT
SPECIAL EFFECTS AND MORE ABOUT
EXTREME WEATHER LIKE SUPERSTORM
SANDY AND THE FLOODS THAT
PLAGUED THE SOUTH AND THE EAST.
YOU SAW ALL OF THOSE SPECIAL
EFFECTS THERE AND THAT'S WHAT
THEY THINK IT'S GOING TO BE
LIKE.
ROBERT, YOUR ORGANIZATION
COMPLETED A SURVEY THAT SHOWS
THAT MORE THAN A THIRD OF
AMERICANS BELIEVE THAT THE
NATURAL DISASTERS IS EVIDENCE OF
END TIMES.
>> YOU'RE RIGHT.
MORE THAN ONE-THIRD, 33%, SAID
THAT INCREASING OF STORMS REALLY
IS EVIDENCE OF THE END TIMES,
THAT IS THE BEGINNING OF THE END
AS WE KNOW IT.
THAT'S MORE THAN 85 MILLION
AMERICANS.
AMONG THIS GROUP, ONE REALLY
STANDS OUT.
THAT IS WHITE EVANGELICAL
PROTESTANTS.
MORE THAN ONE-THIRD BELIEVE THIS
AS A MINORITY OF PROTESTANTS.
IT'S FAR FROM BEING A FRINGE
BELIEF IN AMERICA.
>> HAS THERE BEEN ANY SHIFT IN
ATTITUDES THAT IS, DO MORE
AMERICANS BELIEVE IN A BIBLICAL
EXPLANATION RATHER THAN JUST
GLOBAL WARMING, SOMETHING THAT
WE CAN FIX?
DO THEY THINK IT A BIBLICAL
EXPLANATION?
>> WE ASKED THIS QUESTION
SEPARATELY BECAUSE THEY TOLD US
WHETHER IT WAS A RESULT OF
CLIMATE CHANGE AND A RESULT OF
THE END TIMES AND WE DID SEE
THAT SIX IN TEN AMERICANS SAY
THAT IT'S A RESULT OF CLIMATE
CHANGE.
SO WE HAVE MOST AMERICANS ON
THAT SIDE.
AGAIN, THE SIGNIFICANT MINORITY
HERE AND THE REAL QUESTION IS
HOW MUCH DOES IT MATTER IN TERM
OF WHAT GOVERNMENT ACTION WANTS
TO DO AND IT TURNS OUT THAT IT
MATTERS.
THE PERCEPTION OF THE FACTS
MATTERS THE MOST.
SO THOSE WHO DON'T BELIEVE THAT
STORMS ARE GETTING MORE SEVERE,
JUST THE FACT OF THAT ARE TWICE
AS LIKELY TO SAY THAT THE
GOVERNMENT SHOULD DO MORE TO
ADDRESS CLIMATE CHANGE BUT AMONG
THOSE WHO SAY THAT IT'S A SIGN
OF THE END TIMES, THEY ARE
EVENLY DIVIDED ON WHETHER OR NOT
THE GOVERNMENT SHOULD DO
SOMETHING TO ADDRESS THIS
COMPARED TO MORE THAN TWO-THIRDS
OF THOSE WHO SAY IT'S NOT A SIGN
OF THE END TIMES.
>> OKAY.
EVANGELICALS, THERE SEEMS TO BE
A SPLIT IN THE RELIGIOUS
COMMUNITY BECAUSE THEY SAY
WEATHER SHIFTS ARE BIBLICAL
WHILE MAINLINE PROTESTANTS AND
CATHOLICS CLAIM CLIMATE CHANGE.
>> YOU CAN SEE THIS IN THE
ELECTORAL RESULTS AS WELL.
WHITE EVANGELICALS STAND OUT
DIFFERENT THAN CATHOLICS AS YOU
CAN SEE IN THE DATA HERE AS
HAVING THE BIBLICAL WORLD VIEW
THAT GOD IS CONTROL OF ALL OF
THE EVENTS IN THE WORLD AND GOD
IS IN CONTROL OF THE WEATHER AND
THEY HAVE THEOLOGICAL
SIGNIFICANCE FOR THEM IN WAYS
THAT THEY DON'T EVEN FOR OTHER
RELIGIOUS AMERICANS.
>> HMM.
OKAY.
SO WE WERE TALKING ABOUT THE
DIFFERENT BETWEEN CLIMATE CHANGE
AND WHETHER IT'S BIBLICAL BUT
SOME PEOPLE VIEW CLIMATE CHANGE
AS BIBLICAL.
ARE THE TWO MUTUALLY EXCLUSIVE?
>> YOU KNOW, THEY ARE NOT.
THIS IS ALSO AN INTERESTING
THING OF THE SURVEY, IS THAT WE
HAD ABOUT A FIFTH OF
EVANGELICALS WHO WILL CLAIM
BOTH, THAT THE SEVERITY OF
STORMS IS DUE TO CLIMATE CHANGE
AND IT'S ALSO DUE TO BEING IN
THE BIBLICAL END TIME.
THESE ARE NOT MUTUALLY EXCLUSIVE
ANSWERS WHERE THEY CAN SAY,
MAYBE GOD IS USING THE SEVERITY
OF TIMES AS A MEANS TO GETTING
TO THE END OF TIMES.
>> OKAY.
ROBERT JONES WITH THE PUBLIC
RELIGION RESEARCH INSTITUTE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>>> UP NEXT, A POWERFUL
STATISTIC YOU MAY NOT KNOW.
>> I LOST MY DAD AND UNCLE TO
DRUG ABUSE.
>> I LOST MY UNCAN KELL AND
COUSIN AFTER TWO YEARS OF
PRESCRIPTION DRUG ABUSE.
>> AFTER FAMILY.
>> I LOST BOTH MY MOTHER AND MY
GRANDMOTHER TO OXYCONTIN.
>> PRESCRIPTION DRUG ABUSE
LEAVING THOUSANDS OF CHILDREN
WITHOUT FAMILIES.
DR. SANJAY GUPTA HAS THE STORY,
NEXT.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THE WAY IT MOVES.
THE WAY IT CLEANS.
EVERYTHING ABOUT
THE ORAL-B POWER BRUSH
IS SIMPLY REVOLUTIONARY.
ORAL-B POWER BRUSHES OSCILLATE,
ROTATE
AND EVEN PULSATE
TO GENTLY LOOSEN AND BREAK UP
THAT STICKY PLAQUE
WITH MORE BRUSH MOVEMENTS
THAN MANUAL BRUSHES
AND EVEN
UP TO 50% MORE
THAN LEADING
SONIC TECHNOLOGY BRUSHES
FOR A SUPERIOR CLEAN.
ORAL-B POWER BRUSHES.
GO TO ORALB.COM
FOR THE LATEST OFFERS.
Social Security are just numbers
thinkin a budget.d....
Well, we worked hard for those
benefits.
We earned them.
And if Washington tries to cram
decisions about the future...
of these programs into a last
minute budget deal...
we'll all pay the price.
AARP is fighting to protect
seniors with responsible...
solutions that strengthen
Medicare and...
Social Security for generations
to come.
We can do better than a last
minute deal...
that would hurt all of us.
[ Male Announcer ]
BORN FROM THE ELEMENTS.
♪
DESTINED TO TAKE THEM OVER.
THE UCONNECT COMMAND CENTER
WITH SIRIUS XM SATELLITE RADIO
IN THE NEW 2013 RAM 1500.
ENGINEERED TO MOVE HEAVEN
AND EARTH.
GUTS. GLORY.
RAM.
YOU'LL ALSO CARE ABOUT
OUR NEW OFFER.
YOU GET ACCESS TO NURSES WHO
CAN HELP WITH YOUR QUESTIONS.
AND YOUR LOVED ONE CAN GET
EXELON PATCH FREE FOR 30 DAYS.
IF THE DOCTOR FEELS
IT'S RIGHT FOR THEM.
IT CANNOT CHANGE
HOW THE DISEASE PROGRESSES.
HOSPITALIZATION
AND RARELY DEATH
HAVE BEEN REPORTED IN PATIENTS
WHO WORE MORE THAN ONE PATCH
AT A TIME.
THE MOST COMMON SIDE EFFECTS
OF EXELON PATCH
ARE NAUSEA, VOMITING,
AND DIARRHEA.
THE LIKELIHOOD AND SEVERITY
OF THESE SIDE EFFECTS
MAY INCREASE
AS THE DOSE INCREASES.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
LOSS OF APPETITE OR WEIGHT.
PATIENTS WHO WEIGH
LESS THAN 110 POUNDS
MAY EXPERIENCE
MORE SIDE EFFECTS.
PEOPLE AT RISK
FOR STOMACH ULCERS
WHO TAKE CERTAIN
OTHER MEDICINES
SHOULD TALK TO THEIR DOCTOR
BECAUSE SERIOUS
STOMACH PROBLEMS
SUCH AS BLEEDING MAY WORSEN.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
SLOW HEART RATE.
THIRTY DAYS OF EXELON PATCH
FREE FOR YOUR LOVED ONE.
ACCESS TO TRAINED NURSES
FOR YOU.
CALL 1-855-999-1399
OR VISIT EXELONPATCHOFFER2.COM.
>>> GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE.
I'M DON LEMON.
STORIES WE'RE WATCHING RIGHT NOW
IN THE NEWSROOM, THE U.S. IS
SHOWING ITS SUPPORT FOR TURKEY
IN THE FACE OF POTENTIAL THREATS
FROM SYRIA.
U.S. MILITARY WILL DEPLOY TWO
PATRIOT MISSILE BATTERIES IN THE
COMING WEEKS AND THE MISSILES
ARE TO BE USED JUST FOR DEFENSE.
>> THE TWINKIE AND OTHER HOSTESS
BRAND TREATS COULD BE BACK IN
YOUR LUNCH BAG.
WALMART AND KROGER ARE AMONG THE
DEMAND.
HOSTESS SHUT DOWN AFTER FAILING
TO RESOLVE A CONTRACT DISPUTE
WITH THEIR BAKER.
>>> HOUSE SPEAKER AND PRESIDENT
OBAMA MET JUST UNDER AN HOUR
YESTERDAY.
THEY BOTH DESCRIBED IT AS FRANK
WITH LINES OF COMMUNICATIONS
STAYING OPEN.
>>> MORE THAN 86,000 CHILDREN IN
KENTUCKY ARE LIVING WITHOUT
THEIR PARENT.
THAT IS ACCORDING TO THE 2010
CENSUS.
AND THE REASON WHY MAY SHOCK
YOU.
EXPERTS SAY IT'S BECAUSE OF
PRESCRIPTION DRUG OVERDOSES.
EVERY 19 MINUTES, SOMEONE DIES
THAT WAY HERE IN THE UNITED
STATES.
AND WE'RE USED TO FOCUSING ON
THE PERSON OR WHO DIES.
BUT LOOKING DEEPER, WHAT YOU
FIND ARE HIDDEN, THE VICTIMS.
>> IF THIS TOWN COULD TALK, IT
WOULD DESCRIBE A SIMPLE, IDEALIC
LIFE.
IT WOULD ALSO WHISPER A SOBERING
STORY, AN EPIDEMIC THAT IS
TEARING APART FAMILY --
>> I LOST MY DAD AND UNCLE TO
DRUG ABUSE.
>> AFTER FAMILY.
>> I LOST BOTH MY UNCLE AND
COUSIN AFTER TWO YEARS OF
PRESCRIPTION DRUG ABUSE.
>> AFTER FAMILY.
>> I LOST BOTH MY MOTHER AND MY
GRANDMOTHER TO OXYCONTIN.
>> IT IS NOT UNCOMMON TO HEAR
STORIES LIKE THIS ECHOING DOWN
THE HALLWAYS EVERY DAY AT THIS
HIGH SCHOOL IN ROCK CASTLE
COUNTY, KENTUCKY.
>> CONSTANTLY HEARING ABOUT
SOMEONE ELSE DYING BECAUSE OF
SOMEONE ABUSING PRESCRIPTION
DRUGS.
>> AVERY BRADSHAW SHOWS THIS
STORY ALL TOO WELL.
>> MY GRANDPA SAT ME DOWN AND
TOLD ME THAT HE WAS GONE.
>> WHEN AVERY WAS JUST 7, HIS
FATHER OVERDOSED ON OXYCONTIN.
HE SAYS HIS MOTHER WAS IN AND
OUT OF HIS LIFE.
>> THE HARDEST PART OF GROWING
UP WITHOUT A DAD WOULD BE NOT
HAVING THAT MODEL FAMILY LIKE
THAT YOU ALWAYS SEE.
>> HE'S LUCKY ENOUGH TO LIVE
WITH HIS GREAT GRAND PARENT.
IN THIS TOWN, THAT MODEL FAMILY
IS BEING REDEFINED.
>> THIS IS HAPPENING IN
ROCKCASTLE COUNTY EVERY WEEK BUT
IT'S HAPPENING IN EASTERN
KENTUCKY EVERY DAY.
IT'S LEAVING OUR COMMUNITIES IN
SHREDS AND WE'RE LEFT BEHIND TO
PICK UP THE PIECESES FROM THAT.
>> KAREN KELLY IS THE EXECUTIVE
DIRECTOR OF OPERATION UNITE, A
COMMITTEE FORMED TO HELP PREVENT
OVERDOSES IN KENTUCKY.
KENTUCKY IS THE FOURTH MOST
MEDICATED STATE IN THE UNITED
STATES AND IN ONE COUNTY
ALONE --
>> HALF OF THE KIDS HAVE NO
PARENT IN THE HOME WHATSOEVER.
SO NOW WE'RE SEEING MANY RAISED
BY GREAT GRAND PARENT BECAUSE
WE'VE LOST AN ENTIRE GENERATION
OF YOUNG PEOPLE AND, YOU KNOW,
THE KIDS ARE REALLY THE ONES
PAYING THE BIGGEST PRICE.
>> IT'S STRESSFUL FOR KIDS AND
IT'S REALLY AN EMOTIONAL THING.
>> DR. SANJAY GUPTA, CNN,
REPORTING.
>> YOU CAN SEE MORE REPORTING
FROM DR. GUPTA THIS WEEKEND.
IT AIRS SATURDAY AFTERNOON, 4:30
P.M.
YOU JUST SAW KAREN KELLY TALKING
ABOUT THIS PROBLEM.
SHE JOINS ME NOW LIVE VIA SKYPE.
SHE IS THE DIRECTOR OF THE
OPERATION UNITE, A NONPROFIT
FOCUSED ON TEACHING PEOPLE ABOUT
THE DANGERS OF DRUG ABUSE.
WHAT IS THE BIGGEST STRUGGLE IN
FIGHTING DRUG ABUSE?
>> WELL, WE CREATE MORE ADDICTS
EVERY DAY BECAUSE OF THIS
PROBLEM AND IT'S SOMETHING THAT
WE'VE TALKED TO A LOT OF PARENT
WHO HAVE LOST CHILDREN BUT WE
TEND TO LEAVE THE CHILDREN OUT
OF FOCUS AND IT'S SOMETHING THAT
IS JUST HEART-WRENCHING BECAUSE
WHAT DO YOU DO WITH THESE KIDS?
HOW CAN THEY GO TO SCHOOL AND
FOCUS ON MATH OR READING WHEN
THEY DON'T HAVE PARENTS AT HOME?
>> HOW IS THIS DIFFERENT, A
DIFFERENT BATTLE COMPARED TO
HEROIN, METH, OR ALCOHOL?
>> WELL, BECAUSE, AS I
MENTIONED, WE CREATE NEW ADDICTS
EVERY DAY AND MANY PEOPLE GET
ADDICTED THROUGH LEGITIMATE
MEANS, LEGITIMATE PRESCRIPTIONS
BECAUSE OF A CAR ACCIDENT OR A
BACK INJURY AND THEN THE NEXT
THING YOU KNOW THEY ARE
STRUGGLING TO KEEP THEIR LIVES
IN CONTROL.
AND IT'S JUST SOMETHING -- LEGAL
DRUGS IS OUR BIGGEST PROBLEM IN
THIS COUNTRY RIGHT NOW.
>> GIVE US A SOLUTION, IF YOU
HAVE A FAMILY MEMBER -- WE HAVE
TO GO ON.
WE HAVE BREAKING NEWS.
BUT JUST A SOLUTION AS YOU LEAVE
US.
>> IF YOU HAVE MEDICATIONS IN
YOUR HOME, LOCK THEM UP AND MAKE
SURE THAT YOU CHECK INTO OTHER
OPTIONS BEFORE YOUR DOCTOR WANT
TO PRESCRIBE YOU OPEN PIATES.
>> KAREN, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
BUT WE HAVE BREAKING NEWS.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> THIS IS CNN, BREAKING NEWS.
>> IT IS JUST COMING ACROSS THE
WIRES HERE, FROM THE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE, RESPONDING TO
REPORTS OF A SHOOTING, WE ARE
TOLD, AT NEWTON ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL THIS MORNING.
IT'S IN THE SOUTHWESTERN PART OF
CONNECTICUT.
THAT'S ACCORDING TO A POLICE
SPOKESMAN, RESPONDING TO REPORTS
OF A SHOOTING AT NEWTOWN
ELEMENTALLY SCHOOL.
THERE IS A MAP RIGHT THERE.
SANDY HOOK.
LET ME READ MORE OF WHAT I'M
GETTING HERE.
ACCORDING TO ONE OF OUR
AFFILIATES, THE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE ARE RESPONDING TO
THAT SHOOTING AT NEWTOWN.
EXCUSE ME.
NOT NEWTON.
NEWTOWN.
THE SHOOTING HAPPENED ON
DICKINSON.
IT'S NEWTOWN.
I SAID NEWTON BEFORE BUT IT'S
NEWTOWN.
WE DON'T KNOW IF THERE'S ANY
INJURIES BUT THEY ARE DEPLOYING
UNITS AND CNN IS SENDING CREWS
AND OUR AFFILIATES ARE SENDING
CREWS AS WELL.
THEY ARE EN ROUTE TO AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN.
WE ARE WORKING OUR SOURCES AND
OUR AFFILIATES THERE IN THE AREA
TO TRY TO FIGURE OUT WHAT IS
GOING ON.
AS YOU KNOW, LAW ENFORCEMENT --
AND WE DO HERE AT CNN AND ALL
NEWS ORGANIZATIONS TAKE IT VERY
SERIOUSLY ANY TIME THERE ARE
REPORTS OF A GUN OR SHOTS FIRED
AT A SCHOOL, ELEMENTARY, JUNIOR
HIGH SCHOOL, COLLEGE, WHAT HAVE
YOU.
AND THAT'S WHAT WE ARE DOING
RIGHT NOW, CHECKING ON THAT FOR
YOU.
WE'RE GETTING SOME INFORMATION
IN.
OUR PRODUCERS ARE GATHERING IT
FOR US.
WE'LL BE BACK WITH THE VERY
LATEST ON THE OTHER SIDE OF THIS
BREAK.
DON'T GO ANYWHERE.
[ Female Announcer ] BORN
FROM THE SWEET MONK FRUIT,
SOMETHING THIS DELICIOUS
COULD ONLY COME FROM NATURE.
NEW NECTRESSE.
THE 100% NATURAL
NO-CALORIE SWEETENER
MADE FROM THE GOODNESS
OF FRUIT.
NEW NECTRESSE.
SWEETNESS NATURALLY.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OUR TENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
WE BELIEVE THE MORE YOU KNOW,
THE BETTER YOU TRADE.
SO WE HAVE ONGOING WEBINARS
AND INTERACTIVE LEARNING,
PLUS, IN-BRANCH SEMINARS
AT OVER 500 LOCATIONS,
WHERE OUR DEDICATED SUPPORT
TEAMS HELP YOU KNOW MORE
SO YOUR MONEY CAN DO MORE.
[ Rodger ] AT SCOTTRADE,
SEVEN DOLLAR TRADES
ARE JUST THE START.
OUR TEAMS HAVE THE
INFORMATION YOU WANT
WHEN YOU NEED IT.
IT'S ANOTHER REASON
MORE INVESTORS ARE SAYING...
[ All ]
I'M WITH SCOTTRADE.
>>> THE BREAKING NEWS IS COMING
TO US OUT OF CONNECTICUT, THE
SOUTHWESTERN PART OF THAT STATE
WHERE POLICE ARE REPORTING THAT
THEY ARE RESPONDING TO REPORTS
OF A SHOOTING AT NEWTOWN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL EARLY THIS
MORNING.
AGAIN, IN THE SOUTHWESTERN PART
OF THE CONNECTICUT.
THAT IS ACCORDING TO A POLICE
SPOKESMAN LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE.
THE SCHOOL IS ON DICKINSON DRIVE
AND THERE ARE FEW OTHER DETAIL
AVAILABLE.
OUR AFFILIATES ARE ON THE WAY TO
THE SCENE AS WELL AS CNN CREWS,
PHOTOGRAPHERS, CORRESPONDENTS ON
THE WAY TO THIS.
OF COURSE, WE ALL CRINGE WHEN WE
HEAR ABOUT REPORTS OF A
SHOOTING, ESPECIALLY AT AN
ELEMENTARY, ESPECIALLY ANY
ORGANIZATION, A BUSINESS OR A
SCHOOL BUT WHEN YOU LOOK AT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL CHILDREN, SO
YOUNG, AND REPORTS OF A SHOOTING
AT A SCHOOL, WE HAVE VERY FEW
DETAILS ON THIS.
EVEN THE FOLKS IN CONNECTICUT
ARE SCRAMBLING TO TRY TO GET
THEIR BEARINGS AROUND THIS AND
GET TO THE SCENE TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT IS GOING ON.
AGAIN, THIS IS NEWTOWN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE REPORTS CAME IN,
APPROXIMATELY, 30 MINUTES AGO.
IT'S SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
IS THAT CORRECT?
BRIAN, MY PRODUCER?
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY IN
NEWTOWN.
AGAIN, IN THE SOUTHWESTERN PART
OF THE STATE.
VERY FEW DETAILS ABOUT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY, HOW BIG IT IS,
HOW MANY STUDENTS, WHAT GRADES,
IF IT IS FROM FIRST TO NINE OR
WHAT HAVE YOU.
AGAIN, REPORTS FROM OUR
AFFILIATES ARE TELLING US WHERE
IT IS AND THERE ARE ALSO OTHER
REPORTS OUT THERE -- AGAIN, THIS
IS NOT CNN'S REPORTING.
THIS IS OTHER PUBLISHED REPORTS
THAT I'M LOOKING ON THE WIRES,
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL DISTRICT IS
ON LOCKDOWN, PEOPLE ARE
REPORTING, FOLLOWING A SHOOTING
AT AN ELEMENTARY REPORT.
THEY ARE SAYING IT'S AN
UNCONFIRMED REPORT BUT WE HAVE A
CONFIRMED REPORT THAT THEY ARE
RESPONDING TO THE SHOOTING
THERE.
THE DISTRICT IS TAKING
PREVENTIVE MEASURES BY PUTTING
ALL SCHOOLS ON LOCKDOWN UNTIL
THEY ENSURE THE SAFETY OF ALL
STUDENTS.
AGAIN, THAT'S ACCORDING TO
ANOTHER REPORT THAT IS QUOTING
THE NEWTOWN PUBLIC SCHOOL
DISTRICT OF SUPERINTENDENT.
THE POLICE DEPARTMENT IS SENDING
UNITS FOLLOWING A SHOOTING AT A
THAT SCHOOL AND ALL PRIVATE AND
PUBLIC SCHOOLS IN TOWN ARE ON
LOCKDOWN.
THEY SAID THERE IS A MESSAGE.
WE CAN LOOK FOR THIS IF YOU GUYS
ARE ON THE SCHOOL'S WEBSITE.
A MESSAGE ON THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT'S WEBSITE THAT ALL
AFTERNOON KINDERGARTEN IS
CANCELED AND NO MIDDAY BUS RUNS.
YOU ARE LOOKING AT THE SCHOOL'S
WEBSITE THERE.
UP ON THE TOP RIGHT OF YOUR
SCREEN, YOU CAN SEE IT IN THE
YELLOW PART, AFTERNOON
KINDERGARTEN IS CANCELED TODAY.
THERE WILL BE NO MIDDAY BUS
RUNSES.
SO I'M NOT SURE IF THAT IS
BECAUSE OF THESE REPORTS OF A
SHOOTING.
BUT IT IS AN INDICATION THAT
SOMETHING IS GOING ON, THAT
SOMETHING IS AWRY IN THIS SCHOOL
DISTRICT.
AGAIN, SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT THE SCHOOL'S
WEBSITE.
REPORTS OF A SHOOTING AT THAT
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL WHICH IS
LOCATED IN THE SOUTHWESTERN PART
OF THE STATE AND WE'VE CONFIRMED
THAT FROM POLICE SPOKESMAN
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE.
WE HAVE CREWS ON THE WAY TO THE
SCRE
SCENE.
OUR AFFILIATES HAVE CREWS ON THE
WAY TO THE SCENE AS WELL.
WE HAVE A REPORTER IN NEW YORK
WHO IS FOLLOWING THAT FOR US AND
WE'LL GET THAT REPORTER TO YOU
AS WELL ON THE OTHER SIDE OF
THIS BREAK.
DON'T GO AWAY.
BREAKING NEWS HERE ON CNN.
Employees are being forced to do
more with less.
And the need for capable leaders
is greater than ever.
When you see these problems do
you take a step back,
or do you want to dive right in?
With a degree in business from
Capella University, you'll have
the knowledge to go further in
your career than you ever
thought possible.
Let's get started at CAPELLA.EDU
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
♪ HARK HOW THE BELLS,
SWEET SILVER BELLS ♪
♪ ALL SEEM TO SAY
THROW CARE AWAY ♪
♪ FROM EVERYWHERE,
FILLING THE AIR ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
CHEX PARTY MIX.
EASY 15-MINUTE
HOMEMADE RECIPES
YOU JUST POP IN A MICROWAVE.
LIKE CARAMEL CHOCOLATE
DRIZZLES.
HAPPIER HOLIDAYS.
CHEX PARTY MIX.
>>> THE BREAKING NEWS HERE ON
CNN IS THAT CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE HAVE RESPONDED TO REPORTS
OF A SHOOTING AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
IT'S IN THE NEWTOWN SCHOOL
DISTRICT IN THE SOUTHWESTERN
PART OF CONNECTICUT.
FIRST PICTURES COMING IN RIGHT
NOW.
LET'S PUT THEM UP.
YOU SEE THE POLICE TAPE IN FRONT
AND YOU SEE ALSO EMERGENCY
PEOPLE IN THE BACKGROUND THERE.
A FIRE TRUCK ON YOUR LEFT.
FIRE AND RESCUE.
SO IT APPEARS THROUGH THESE
PICTURES -- ANOTHER CONFIRMATION
THAT SOMETHING IS GOING ON AT
THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN.
THIS PICTURE, COURTESY OF OUR
AFFILIATE WCCT.
AGAIN, WE HAVE VERY FEW DETAILS
ABOUT THIS SHOOTING.
IT'S JUST THAT THERE WERE
REPORTS FOR POLICE TO COME OUT
BECAUSE OF SOME SORT OF
DISTURBANCE OR SHOOTING AT THE
SCHOOL.
OBVIOUSLY POLICE INVESTIGATORS,
FIRE DEPARTMENT ALL RUSHING OUT
TO THE SCHOOL AND FINDING WHAT
THEY FOUND AND WE DON'T HAVE THE
INFORMATION OF WHAT THEY HAVE
FOUND YET.
THERE ARE OTHER REPORTS
PUBLISHED AND OTHERWISE THAT ARE
SAYING THAT THE SCHOOL DISTRICT
IS ON LOCKDOWN.
THE SCHOOL DISTRICT IS ON
LOCKDOWN RIGHT NOW.
NEWTOWN POLICE SPOKESMAN IS
TELLING CNN, OUR NEW YORK DESK,
THAT POLICE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY RESPONDED TO THAT
SHOOTING AND THE KIDS ARE NOT
BEING EVACUATED.
THE KIDS ARE NOT BEING EVACUATED
FROM THIS SCHOOL.
SO, AGAIN, WE ARE GETTING NEW
INFORMATION NOW COMING IN.
THESE ARE THE FIRST PICTURES
COMING IN FROM THE SCHOOL.
WE DON'T KNOW IF THERE ARE ANY
INJURIES.
WE DON'T KNOW THE DETAILS BEHIND
THE SHOOTING, WHAT TYPE OF GUN
IF AT ALL, WHO THE SUSPECT WAS,
IF IT WAS A STUDENT.
AGAIN, WHEN WE GET REPORTS LIKE
THIS, WE ALL CRINGE BECAUSE IT'S
THE LAST THING YOU WANT TO SEE
HAPPEN AT ANY BUSINESS OR HOME
AND ESPECIALLY AT AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL WHEN WE KNOW THE AGES OF
THE PEOPLE INVOLVED AND WE SEND
OUR KIDS OFF TO SCHOOL EVERY
SINGLE DAY HOPING THAT THEY WILL
BE IN THE BEST HANDS AND THEN
SADLY, FROM TIME TO TIME, THESE
TERRIBLE SITUATIONS DO CROP UP.
AGAIN, WE ARE LEARNING THAT THIS
SCHOOL IS ON LOCKDOWN.
CNN HAS CONFIRMED THAT THEY ARE
NOT EVACUATING THE STUDENTS FROM
THE SCHOOL.
EMERGENCY PERSONNEL ARE THERE.
OTHERS ARE STILL BEING RUSHED
THERE.
OUR AFFILIATE ARE ON THE WAY TO
THE SCHOOL AS WELL AS CNN CREWS
AND PERSONNEL ON THE WAY AS
WELL.
JUST TO GIVE YOU AN IDEA, YOU'VE
BEEN SEEING THE MAP THERE.
THE ONLY THING WE KNOW IS THAT
IT IS IN THE SOUTHWESTERN PART
OF CONNECTICUT.
AND IF YOU GUYS -- I'M IN A
BUBBLE BY MYSELF.
IF YOU CAN SHOW US HOW CLOSE WE
ARE TO A MAJOR TOWN OR CITY, TO
GIVE US AN IDEA OF WHERE THIS
SCHOOL IS AND HOW MANY STUDENTS
ARE THERE.
AGAIN, HERE'S THE LATEST FROM
THE WIRES.
FROM THE CNN WIRES.
AND THEY ARE SAYING CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE AND LOCAL
AUTHORITIES ARE RESPONDING TO A
SHOOTING AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN SOUTHWESTERN
CONNECTICUT.
THE SCHOOL IS SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
IT IS ON LOCKDOWN.
THEY ARE NOT BEING EVACUATED.
THAT'S ACCORDING TO A NEWTOWN
POLICE SPOKESMAN.
OUR WIRES ARE SAYING NEWTON BUT
IT IS NEWTOWN.
IT APPEARS TO NOT BE VERY CLOSE
TO A CITY CENTER BECAUSE OUR
AFFILIATES ARE TELLING US THAT
IT'S GOING TO TAKE THEM A COUPLE
MINUTES TO GET TO THE SCENE, 30
MINUTES.
IF IT WAS CLOSE TO A MAJOR CITY,
IT WOULD NOT TAKE THAT LONG TO
GET OUT TO THIS ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
AS YOU KNOW, THE MEDIA IS
USUALLY LOCATED IN LARGER URBAN
AREAS AND BUSINESS AREAS AND
THIS MUST BE A SMALLER TOWN IN
ORDER FOR -- OKAY.
WE'RE TRYING TO GET SOMEONE ON
THE PHONE NOW, LOU, A FORMER NEW
YORK POLICE OFFICER.
IS LOU ON THE PHONE NOW OR ARE
WE STILL WORKING TO GET HIM?
SAY AGAIN?
ALMOST THERE.
OKAY.
AS WE WORK -- LET ME KNOW IN MY
EAR WHEN WE GET LOU.
SO, AGAIN, THOSE ARE THE REPORTS
THAT WE HAVE AND THIS COMES TO
US AS WE WERE OBVIOUSLY IN THE
MIDDLE OF OTHER NEWS ABOUT
WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN WITH THE
FISCAL CLIFF AND WHAT HAVE YOU
AND THEN ALL OF A SUDDEN THIS
DISTURBING NEWS COMES ACROSS THE
WIRES AND WE HAVE TO READJUST TO
BRING THIS TO YOU.
LOU, I KNOW YOU VERY WELL.
YOU HAVE KIDS.
I'VE MET YOUR WIFE AND YOUR
KIDS.
WE SEND OUR KIDS OFF TO SCHOOL
EVERY DAY.
THIS IS THE WORST THING, THE
WORST NEWS THAT WE CAN GET.
>> I'M HERE, DON.
>> YEAH.
LOU, TALK TO ME ABOUT THIS
SWAYING.
I'M NOT SURE IF YOU'RE WORKING
YOUR SOURCES.
BUT AS I SAID, I'M NOT SURE IF
YOU CAN HEAR ME, YOU HAVE KIDS,
I'VE MET YOUR KIDS, I'VE MET
YOUR WIFE.
I KNOW HOW MUCH YOU LOVE THEM.
YOU SEND YOUR KIDS OFF TO SCHOOL
AND THEN ALL OF A SUDDEN YOU GET
THIS NEWS AND THIS IS THE WORST
NEWS THAT YOU CAN GET.
>> THIS IS THE GREATEST FEAR,
DON, YOU CAN POSSIBLY HAVE.
IF YOU WATCH OUR CULTURE, IT
SEEMS LIKE IT'S ERODING AWAY.
YOU CAN'T TAKE KIDS TO THE MOVIE
THEATER OR SHOPPINGI AT THE MAL.
VERY INTERESTING CULTURE WE HAVE
EVOLVED INTO.
>> DO YOU KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT
THIS SCHOOL DISTRICT?
>> I'M SLIGHTLY FAMILIAR WITH IT
BECAUSE AT ONE TIME I DID HAVE A
RESIDENCE IN CONNECTICUT, AS YOU
ARE PROBABLY AWARE.
I THINK THE SCHOOL DISTRICT IS
BORDERLINE ACADEMIC.
THIS IS A GRAMMAR SCHOOL.
IT'S AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE'RE NOT TALKING ABOUT A HIGH
SCHOOL WHERE THE CHILDREN HAVE
EVOLVED A BIT MORE WHERE IF YOU
STIMULATE THEM NEGATIVELY AS
THEY DID IN COLUMBINE, YOU END
UP WITH THIS GROUP THAT CARRY
OUT THESE HEINOUS ACTS OF
KILLING PEOPLE.
THIS IS AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
I'M VERY CURIOUS TO KNOW WHAT
THIS IMPETUS WAS AT THE SCHOOL.
IS IT IN BETWEEN TEACHERS,
WORKPLACE VIOLENCE?
I'M INTERESTED TO SEE WHAT THE
DYNAMICS IS HERE.
>> WHATEVER IT IS, IT'S
DISTURBING.
IT'S AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND
WHEN I WAS GROWING UP, I DON'T
KNOW WHAT THE -- I'M READING
HERE.
I DON'T KNOW HOW EXACTLY THEY DO
IT NOW, WHAT THE MEASURES WERE,
BUT MINE WAS K-5 AND THEN 5-8 OR
9 WAS JUNIOR HIGH SCHOOL AND
THEN HIGH SCHOOL WAS BEYOND
THAT.
SO WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT THOSE
AGES, THOSE ARE KIDS ANYWHERE
FROM 4 TO 5 YEARS OLD TO 12 OR
13 YEARS OLD.
THAT'S REALLY YOUNG.
>> THAT'S THE SCARY PART, THAT
THEY WOULD BE SUBJECTED TO THAT
IN THIS ENVIRONMENT OF LEARNING.
YOU HAVE TO UNDERSTAND THE RAM
IF I KAGS OF THIS AND THEIR
ABILITY TO GO INTO A LEARNING
ENVIRONMENT, CONCENTRATE, FEEL
SECURE.
WE'RE NOT EVEN TALKING ABOUT THE
PARENTS' STATE OF MIND.
THE THING I SUSPECT, DON, THIS
HAD LITTLE OR NOTHING TO DO WITH
THE CHILDREN PER SE BASED ON THE
DEMOGRAPHIC, THE AGE THERE.
IT PROBABLY IS SOMETHING TO DO
WITH THE TEACHERS OR MAYBE THERE
WAS AN OUTSIDE INFLUENCE OR
ISSUE INTRODUCED INTO THA
SCHOOL ENVIRONMENT WHERE A
SHOOTER, FOR EXAMPLE, MAY HAVE
GONE IN FOR A PERSON THEY WERE
LOOKING FOR WHO JUST HAPPENED TO
BE IN THAT ENVIRONMENT.
THIS IS ALWAYS GOING TO BE THE
FRUITION OF THE INVESTIGATION.
RIGHT NOW WHAT WE'RE SEEING,
DON, IS THE POLICE ARE
RESPONDING, THEY ARE CREATING A
PERIMETER, THEY ARE -- HOW WOULD
YOU SAY -- EXERCISING
CONTAINMENT.
WHICH MEANS THEY ARE GOING TO
PREVENT ANY OUTSIDE -- FURTHER
OUTSIDE INFLUENCE INTO THE
SCHOOL.
>> LOU, HOLD THAT THOUGHT.
HOLD THAT THOUGHT AND I'LL GET
TO YOU ON THE OTHER SIDE OF THE
BREAK.
STAY WITH US FOR THE BREAKING
NEWS HERE ON CNN.
AMERICANS BELIEVE THEY SHOULD BE
IN CHARGE OF THEIR OWN FUTURE.
HOW THEY'LL LIVE TOMORROW.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
>>> AND THE BREAKING NEWS HERE
ON CNN, CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
RESPONDING TO REPORTS OF A
SHOOTING AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN THE NEWTOWN
SCHOOL DISTRICT IN SOUTHWESTERN
CONNECTICUT THIS MORNING.
THERE ARE PICTURES FROM THE
SCENE.
THERE YOU SEE ON THE RIGHT OF
YOUR SCREEN, YOU SEE THE POLICE
TAPE AND THE EMERGENCY
OFFICIALS.
OUR REPORTING IS THAT POLICE
RESPONDED EARLIER TO THIS
SHOOTING AND THAT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IS ON LOCKDOWN RIGHT NOW.
THERE ARE OTHERS THAT ARE
REPORTING THIS IS ABC REPORTING,
AGAIN, THAT IS ON LOCKDOWN AND
THAT'S ACCORDING TO THE
SECRETARY AND THEY SAY STATE
POLICE ARE SENDING UNITS TO THAT
AREA.
ALL PRIVATE AND PUBLIC SCHOOLS
ARE ON LOCKDOWN.
ABC IS REPORTING THAT.
WE'RE REPORTING THAT THIS ONE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IS ON LOCKDOWN
BECAUSE OF THIS BUT THEY ARE NOT
EVACUATING ANY CHILDREN OUT OF
THIS SCHOOL.
DON'T KNOW THE EXTENT OF ANY
INJURIES AND WE DON'T KNOW THE
DETAILS BEHIND THE SHOOTING, WHO
EXACTLY DID IT AND WHY.
LOU, LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIAL
FAMILIAR HERE AT CNN, TALK TO ME
ABOUT THIS SCHOOL DISTRICT.
YOU KNOW IT BECAUSE YOU HAVE A
RESIDENCE IN CONNECTICUT?
>> YEAH.
I'M FAMILIAR WITH IT, DON.
THERE'S NOTHING GERMAIN TO THE
SCHOOL DISTRICT.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT AN HE WI
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
IT'S NOT LIKE WE HAVE THE HIGH
SCHOOL DENOMINATOR THAT HAS
BULLYING.
>> LOU, YOU'RE RIGHT ABOUT THAT
AND WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO GET
OTHER INFORMATION ON THE OTHER
SIDE OF THIS BREAK WHEN WE
CONTINUE WITH ASHLEIGH BANFIELD.
THANK YOU FOR WATCHING.
IF YOU THINK RUNNING
A RESTAURANT IS HARD,
TRY RUNNING FOUR.
FORTUNATELY WE'VE GOT INK.
IT GIVES US 5X THE REWARDS
ON OUR INTERNET, PHONE
CHARGES AND CABLE,
PLUS AT OFFICE SUPPLY STORES.
REWARDS WE PUT RIGHT
BACK INTO OUR BUSINESS.
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
WE'VE EVER WANTED TO DO
AND INK HELPS US DO IT.
MAKE YOUR MARK
WITH INK FROM CHASE.
WELCOME TO CHEVY'S
YEAR-END EVENT.
SO, THE 5.3-LITER V8 SILVERADO
CAN TOW UP TO 9,600 POUNDS?
315 HORSEPOWER.
WHAT'S THAT IN
REINDEER-POWER?
[ laughs ]
[ pencil scratches ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHEVY'S GIVING MORE.
GET THE BEST OFFER
OF THE YEAR --
0% APR FINANCING FOR 60 MONTHS
PLUS $1,000 HOLIDAY BONUS CASH.
PLUS TRADE UP FOR AN ADDITIONAL
$1,000 TRADE-IN ALLOWANCE.
HURRY.
BONUS CASH ENDS JANUARY 2ND.