TO FEEL AND GRACE MY FEARS
RELIEVED ♪
♪ HOW PRECIOUS DID THAT GRACE
APPEAR, THE HOUR I FIRST
BELIEVED ♪
>> "AMAZING GRACE."
THAT DOES IT FOR US.
THANKS VERY MUCH FOR WATCHING. .
THANKS VERY MUCH FOR WATCHING.
"EARLY START" BEGINS NOW.
>>> COULD NEWTOWN BE THE TIPPING
POINT FOR GUN CONTROL?
THE WHITE HOUSE, A MAJOR
RETAILER, NATIONAL POLLS AND
EVEN SOME PRO-GUN LAWMAKERS HAVE
SHIFTED.
FIRST, CAUTIOUS STEP FOR SCHOOL
KIDS IN NEWTOWN.
MOST OF THEM HEAD BACK TO SCHOOL
JUST HOURS FROM NOW.
AND IS IT A BREAKTHROUGH FOR
FISCAL CLIFF TALKS?
THE TWO SIDES CLOSER THAN EVER
WITH JUST TWO WEEKS LEFT TO GO.
>>> GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE.
WELCOME TO "EARLY START."
I'M JOHN BERMAN HERE IN NEW
YORK.
>> AND I'M ZORAIDA SAMBOLIN,
LIVE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE'LL BE BRINGING YOU THE VERY
LATE EF ON THE INVESTIGATION AS
JOHN SAID, THE CHILDREN ARE
STARTING SCHOOL AS WELL WITH AN
INCREASED POLICE PRESENCE, WILL
IT BE ENOUGH FOR THE PARENTS AND
OF COURSE WE HAVE ANOTHER
FUNERAL WE ARE FOLLOWING THIS
MORNING FOR YOU AS WELL.
JOHN?
>> ANOTHER BEAUTIFUL YOUNG CHILD
WE BURIED UP THERE, FOUR DAYS
AFTER THE SCHOOL MASSACRE THAT
NUMBED THE ENTIRE NATION.
THIS IS THE LATEST.
THIS UNSPEAKABLE TRAGEDY IS
REIGNITING THE GUN CONTROL
DEBATE ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
PRESIDENT ALREADY TAKING STEPS
TO BAN ASSAULT RIFLES WITH HIS
VICE PRESIDENT LEADING THE
CHARGE.
PLUS, THIS BRAND NEW OVERNIGHT,
DICK'S SPORTING GOODS HAS BANNED
THE SALE OF AR-15 RIFLES AND
OTHER GUNS LIKE IT FOR NOW.
THE MODERN SPORTING RIFLE
SECTION OF ITS WEBSITE, TOTALLY
BLANK THIS MORNING.
THE COMPANY RELEASING A
STATEMENT SAYING, QUOTE, OUT OF
RESPECT FOR THE VICTIMS AND
THEIR FAMILIES WE HAVE REMOVED
ALL GUNS IN OUR STORE NEAREST TO
NEWTOWN AND SUSPENDED THE SALE
OF MODERN SPORTING RIFLES IN ALL
OF OUR STORES CHAINWIDE.
>>> GRIEF COUNSELORS WILL BE ON
HAND THIS MORNING.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
REMAINS CLOSED.
JESSICA REKOS WILL BE LAID TO
REST TODAY.
SHE COULDN'T WAIT UNTIL HER 10th
BIRTHDAY TO GET A HORSE.
SHE ADORED THEM.
>>> ANOTHER BIG STORY OUT OF
WASHINGTON WHERE THERE'S BEEN
HUGE MOVEMENT IN THE FISCAL
CLIFF WRANGLING WITH 14 DAYS
LEFT TO GO BEFORE HUGE
ACROSS-THE-BOARD TAX HIKES.
OVERNIGHT WE LEARNED THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA MADE AN
EYE-OPENING NEW OFFER IN TALKS
WITH HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER.
UNDER THIS NEW PROPOSAL, TAX
RATES WOULD GO UP ON INCOMES
ABOVE $400,000.
FOR YEARS THE PRESIDENT HAS
CAMPAIGNED THAT THAT NUMBER
SHOULD START AT $250,000.
HE'S ALSO OFFERING SOME NEW
SPENDING CUTS TO GO ALONG WITH
THIS.
SPEAKER BOEHNER'S LATEST
PROPOSAL CALLED FOR THE TAX
HIKES TO KICK IN AT $1 MILLION.
CNN'S DAN LOTHIAN IS IN
WASHINGTON WITH THE LATEST ON
THIS.
DAN, IT REALLY DOES LOOK LIKE
THERE IS SOME MOVEMENT.
>> IT DOES.
THIS MOVEMENT CAME DURING A
MEETING THE PRESIDENT HAD WITH
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER YESTERDAY
AT THE WHITE HOUSE.
THAT MEETING LASTED FOR 45
MINUTES.
IT WAS THE THIRD TIME THEY HAD
MET IN THE PAST EIGHT DAYS.
YOU'RE RIGHT, IT IS PRETTY
DRAMATIC BECAUSE THE PRESIDENT
FOR YEARS NOW HAD BEEN HOLDING
STEADFAST TO THAT $250,000
THRESHOLD, SAYING THAT THE BUSH
ERA TAX CUTS WOULD EXTEND FOR
THEM BUT NOT THOSE HOUSEHOLDS
MAKING MORE THAN THAT.
NOW HE RAISES IT TO $400,000.
SO THAT IS SEEN AS A MAJOR
BREAKTHROUGH.
BUT REPUBLICANS, WHILE
ENCOURAGED BY THESE LATEST
DEVELOPMENTS, ALSO SAY THAT THE
MATH REALLY DOESN'T ADD UP.
THAT THE PRESIDENT'S PROPOSAL
LEANS MORE HEAVILY TOWARDS NEW
TAXES.
NOW, AS PART OF THAT PROPOSAL
THAT THE PRESIDENT HAS CUT PUT
OUT THERE, HE'S CALLING FOR $1.2
TRILLION IN NEW REVENUE, $1.22
TRILLION IN SPENDING CUTS.BUT
REPUBLICAN AIDES, AGAIN, SAYING
THAT THE MATH DOESN'T QUITE ADD
UP BECAUSE THEY SAY THAT THE
CONSUMER PRICE INDEX OR THE CPI
REALLY INCREASES TAX REVENUE BY
$95 BILLION.
SO WHEN THE PRESIDENT IS TALKING
ABOUT $1.2 TRILLION, THEY'RE
SAYING IT'S MORE LIKE $1.3
TRILLION.
THERE'S STILL DISTANCE THERE
BETWEEN BOTH SIDES BUT MUCH
CLOSER THAN IT WAS A FEW DAYS
AGO, JOHN.
>> DAN, IT DOES SEEM BOTH SIDES
ARE INDICATING THERE IS MOVEMENT
BUT NEITHER SIDE IS WILLING TO
SAY IT'S A COMPLETE BREAKTHROUGH
YET.
WITH JUST 14 DAYS TO GO, SHOULD
WE BE OPTIMISTIC THAT A DEAL
WILL BE REACHED?
>> I CERTAINLY THINK PEOPLE ARE
OPTIMISTIC.
CLEARLY JOHN BOEHNER WILL HAVE
TO GO BACK TO THE CONSERVATIVES
IN HIS PARTY WHO HAVE BEEN
RESISTING ANY MOVEMENT
WHATSOEVER IN TAXES GOING UP ON
WEALTHY AMERICANS.
AND PRESIDENT OBAMA ALSO HAS TO
SORT OF PROD SOME IN HIS PARTY
AND THE LAEB UNIONS AND OTHERS
WHO DON'T LIKE WHAT THEY SEE SO
FAR.
OVERALL WHEN YOU LOOK AT THE
DISTANCE THAT WAS THERE BETWEEN
BOTH SIDES, JUST A WEEK AGO,
THERE IS SOME OPTIMISM THAT THIS
CAN GET DONE BEFORE THE END OF
THE YEAR.
>> DAN LOTHIAN IN WASHINGTON
THIS MORNING.
THE HOUSE SPEAKER WILL BE
MEETING WITH HOUSE REPUBLICANS
TODAY.
THAT COULD BE AN INTERESTING AND
CONTENTIOUS MEETING.
THANKS VERY MUCH, DAN.
BACK TO ZORAIDA IN NEWTOWN NOW.
>>> BACK NOW TO THE GUN CONTROL
DEBATE THAT'S BEEN REIGNITED BY
THE MASSACRE AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY RIGHT HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
IT SEEMS MORE AND MORE AMERICANS
ARE MOVING IN THE DIRECTION OF
TIGHTER GUN LAWS IN THIS COUNTRY
IN THE AFTERMATH OF THAT
TRAGEDY.
THIS MORNING WE HAVE LEARNED
THAT PRESIDENT OBAMA IS MOVING
FAST ON GETTING A BAN ON ASSAULT
RIFLES.
THAT IS ACCORDING TO "THE
WASHINGTON POST."
ANOTHER BIG NEW DEVELOPMENT
OVERNIGHT FOR YOU AS WELL,
DICK'S SPORTING GOODS STORE HAS
NOW SUSPENDED THE SALE OF ALL
ASSAULT RIFLES IN ITS STORES.
THIS IS NATIONWIDE.
EMILY SCHMIDT IS LIVE FROM
WASHINGTON RIGHT NOW WITH ALL OF
THE DETAILS.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
>> ZORAIDA, GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
WE HAVE HEARD FROM EVEN
DEMOCRATIC LAWMAKERS THAT THIS
WAS IN NEWTOWN A GAME CHANGER.
WE'RE BEGINNING TO SEE
POTENTIALLY THE IMPACT OF THESE
SHIFTING LANDSCAPES, ESPECIALLY
IN COMMERCIAL WAYS AND POLITICAL
WAYS.
WE START WITH COMMERCIALIZED.
DICK'S SPORTING GOODS, ONE OF
THE NATION'S LARGEST SPORTING
GOODS RETAILERS HAS SAID IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, THE STORE
THAT'S CLOSEST TO THE SHOOTING,
THEY'LL REMOVE ALL GUNS FROM THE
STORES.
NATIONWIDE THEY'LL BE SUSPENDING
THE SALE OF SOME SEMIAUTOMATIC
WEAPONS.
THEY SAY THEY ARE DOING SO OUT
OF RESPECT FOR THE VICTIMS AND
FOR THEIR FAMILIES.
THEN YOU TAKE A LOOK AT WHAT IS
HAPPENING POLITICALLY.
"THE WASHINGTON POST" IS
REPORTING THIS MORNING THAT
YESTERDAY PRESIDENT OBAMA
DIRECTED SOME MEMBERS OF HIS
CABINET TO COME UP WITH
PROPOSALS IMMEDIATELY TO TAKE A
LOOK AT NEW GUN CONTROL
MEASURES, INCLUDING POTENTIALLY
THE END OF THE ASSAULT WEAPONS,
BANNING THAT, AGAIN, AFTER THAT
LAW LAPSED BACK IN 2004.
WE ARE HEARING MORE FROM THE
WHITE HOUSE THAT THEY WANT TO
SEE CHAUMPG IN THIS.
LISTEN TO WHAT THE PRESIDENT
SAID JUST THIS WEEK.
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS,
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT TO MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS TO PARENTS
AND EDUCATORS IN AN EFFORT AIMED
AT PREVENTING MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS.
>> AS WE HEAR MORE ABOUT THIS
FROM WASHINGTON, THE ONE PLACE
WE ARE NOT HEARING ANYTHING
ABOUT IT, ZORAIDA, IS FROM THE
NRA.
THEY'VE NOT MADE A STATEMENT
SENSE A WRITTEN STATEMENT ON
FRIDAY.
THEY'VE SUSPENDED THEIR FACEBOOK
PAGE AND TWITTER FEED HAS
REMAINED SILENT.
ZORAIDA?
>> EMILY, I UNDERSTAND YOU ALSO
HAVE NEW POLLS TO SHARE WITH US
THIS MORNING.
>> WE HAVE THREE DIFFERENT POLLS
THAT ARE REALLY SHOWING A
POTENTIAL SPIKE IN PUBLIC
OPINION CHANGE ON THIS.
I WANT TO START WITH ONE FROM
CBS NEWS THAT WAS TAKEN JUST
OVER THE WEEKEND SAYING DO YOU
THINK GUN CONTROL RULES SHOULD
BE MORE STRICT OR LESS STRICT?
THERE HAS BEEN A SIGNIFICANT
CHANGE IN THIS.
SINCE MORE STRICT, 57% SAY THAT
NOW COMPARED TO 39% BACK IN
APRIL.
THE AMOUNT OF PEOPLE WHO THINK
THE GUN CONTROL SHOULD BE LESS
STRICT HAS DROPPED.
SIMILAR FINDINGS FROM AN ABC
NEWS/"WASHINGTON POST" POLL, DO
YOU SUPPORT OR OPPOSE STRICTER
GUN CONTROL LAWS?
TAKE A LOOK AT HOW THAT NUMBER
HAS GONE UP SINCE AUGUST.
ONE MORE INTERESTING THING, THE
PUGH RESEARCH CENTER ASKED
PEOPLE DO YOU THINK THE
SHOOTINGS REFLECT A LARGER
SOCIETAL PROBLEM IN THEIR POLLS
SAY 47% OF AMERICANS THAT WERE
POLLED THINK IT DOES.
CONTRAST THAT TO WHAT HAPPENED
AFTER THE AURORA SHOOTINGS
EARLIER THIS YEAR.
AT THAT TIME, THE NUMBER JUST
24%.
THE QUESTION IS WHETHER THIS
QUICK SPIKE IN PUBLIC OPINION
CHANGE WILL REFLENGT ANY
LEGISLATIVE CHANGES DOWN THE
LINE.
ZORAIDA?
>> I KNOW A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE
HOPING SO.
EMILY SCHMIDT, LIVE IN
WASHINGTON FOR US.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
6:30 EASTERN SOLEDAD O'BRIEN
WILL BE JOINED BY CONGRESSWOMAN
SHEILA JACKSON LEE.
THE TEXAS DEMOCRAT IS CALLING
FOR AN IMMEDIATE BAN ON ALL
ASSAULT WEAPONS.
SOLEDAD WILL BE JOINED BY
SENATOR JOE MANCHIN, THE WEST
VIRGINIA DEMOCRAT IS AN NRA
MEMBER.
HE SAYS NOW IS THE TIME TO ACT
ON TIGHTENING UP OUR GUN LAWS AS
WELL.
AS WE SAID, NEWTOWN SCHOOLS WILL
RE-OPEN TODAY.
BUT THEY WILL BE OPEN TWO HOURS
LATER THAN USUAL.
SANDY HOOK REMAINS AN ACTIVE
CRIME SCENE.
IT IS STILL CLOSED.
HUNDREDS OF NEWTOWN TEACHERS AND
STAFF MET WITH A NATIONAL EXPERT
ON KIDS AND BEREAVEMENT, AS WELL
AS STATE MENTAL HEALTH
COUNSELORS.
FOR THE STUDENTS AND THEIR
FAMILIES IT IS A RETURN TO
HEALTHY AND HELPFUL ROUTINE.
HERE'S SANDRA ENDO.
>> Reporter: IN THE WAKE OF
TRAGEDY, A STEP TOWARDS
NORMALCY, FOR NEWTOWN KIDS, THAT
MEANS GOING BACK TO SCHOOL.
>> WE ALSO ARE GOING TO BE A
LITTLE BIT WORRIED, BECAUSE WE
KNOW WHAT WE THOUGHT WAS A
SECURE SCHOOL HAD THIS HAPPEN TO
THEM.
>> Reporter: BUT FACING FEAR MAY
BE THE FIRST STEP TO OVERCOME
THIS TRAGEDY.
>> CHILDREN HAVE TO GET BACK TO
SCHOOL.
IF WE LET THIS SORT OF TERROR IN
OUR LIVES ANYWHERE IN THIS
COUNTRY WIN, YOU KNOW, WE'VE
LOST.
WE'VE GOT TO GET OUR KIDS BACK
TO SCHOOL AGAIN.
>> Reporter: CLASSES ARE
RESUMING FOR 5,400 STUDENTS IN
THE DISTRICT EXCEPT FOR THOSE AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
MONDAY ALL SCHOOLS WERE CLOSED
AS TEACHERS AND ADMINISTRATORS
TRAINED WITH EXPERTS ON HOW TO
HANDLE THE AFTERMATH.
MANY PARENTS WE SPOKE WITH
AGREE, KIDS BELONG BACK IN
SCHOOL.
>> I THINK THAT ONE OF THE BIG
THINGS WE HAVE TO DO IS HAVE
SOME SORT OF NORMALCY.
AND SCHOOL IS PART OF THAT.
>> UNFORTUNATELY, YOU KNOW,
WE'RE LIVING IN THIS WORLD WHERE
EVIL PREVAILS SOMETIMES.
BUT WE'RE JUST BELIEVING THAT
GOOD WILL OVERCOME THIS.
>> Reporter: SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY REMAINS A CRIME
SCENE.
FURNITURE AND SUPPLIES WERE
MOVED TO CHALK HILL MIDDLE
SCHOOL IN NEIGHBORING MONROE
WHERE SANDY HOOK STUDENTS WILL
EVENTUALLY RESUME CLASSES.
>> WHEN THE CHILDREN COME IN
WHENEVER THE SCHOOL IS STARTED,
THEY WALK INTO A CLASSROOM THAT
WILL LOOK AS CLOSE AS POSSIBLE
AS THEIR CLASSROOM THEY LEFT.
>> GRIEF COUNSELORS AND POLICE
WILL BE AT NEWTOWN SCHOOLS AS
CLASSES RESUME AND PRINCIPALS
HAVE ASKED PARENTS TO TALK TO
THEIR CHILD BEFORE RETURNING TO
SCHOOL, BECAUSE THEY CAN'T
CONTROL WHAT THEIR CHILD MAY
HEAR AT SCHOOL.
AND TEACHERS WILL BE ADDRESSING
WHAT HAPPENED IN AN AGE
APPROPRIATE MANNER.
ZORAIDA?
>> SANDRA ENDO, LIVE FOR US
HERE.
THANK YOU.
>>> CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR MALLOY
IS CALLING FOR A NATIONWIDE
MOMENT OF SILENCE FRIDAY MORNING
EXACTLY ONE WEEK AFTER THE
SHOOTING AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
HE'S ALSO CALLING ON CHURCHES TO
RING THEIR BELLS 26 TIMES.
OF COURSE THAT IS ONCE FOR EACH
OF THE VIBLTS WHO WERE KILLED IN
FRIDAY'S MASSACRE.
THE GOVERNOR SOUNDING SHAKEN
WHEN HE EXPLAINED IT WHY HE TOOK
IT UPON HIMSELF TO TELL LOVED
ONES THAT THEIR LOVED ONES WAS
NOT COMING OUT.
>> IT WAS EVIDENT TO ME THAT
THERE WAS A RELUCTANCE TO TELL
PARENTS AND LOVED ONES THAT THE
PERSON THEY WERE WAITING FOR WAS
NOT GOING TO RETURN.
I MADE THE DECISION THAT TO HAVE
THAT GO ON ANY LONG ER WAS WRON.
>> MALLOY SAYS HE FULLY SUPPORTS
ACTION AT THE FEDERAL LEVEL TO
TIGHTEN THE NATION'S GUN CONTROL
LAWS.
AND EVERY MASS SHOOTING LEAVES
US ASKING THE EXACT SAME
QUESTION.
WHY?
WHAT DRIVES SOMEONE TO SUCH
VIOLENCE, DOES THE BRAIN HOLD
CLUES FOR US?
LATER THIS HOUR, CHIEF MEDICAL
CORRESPONDENT DR. SANJAY GUPTA
IS GOING TO LOOK AT THAT FOR US.
AND IT'S ANOTHER SIGN THE TIDE
COULDING TURNING AND THE DEBATE
OVER GUN CONTROL IN AMERICA.
COMING UP, THE WALL STREET FIRM
TAKING A STAND, PUTTING POLITICS
AHEAD OF PROFITS.
♪
[ engine revs ]
[ Male Announcer ]
OH WHAT FUN IT IS TO RIDE.
GET THE MERCEDES-BENZ
ON YOUR WISH LIST
AT THE WINTER EVENT GOING ON
NOW THROUGH DECEMBER 31ST.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
E350 FOR $579 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
I just served my mother-in-law
your Chicken Noodle soup
but she loved it so much...
I told her it was homemade.
Everyone tells
a little white lie now and then.
But now she wants
my recipe
[ clears his throat ]
[ softly ]
She's right behind me isn't she?
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
WHO HAVE USED AndroGel 1%,
THERE'S BIG NEWS.
PRESENTING AndroGel 1.62%.
BOTH ARE USED TO TREAT MEN
WITH LOW TESTOSTERONE.
AndroGel 1.62%
IS FROM THE MAKERS
OF THE NUMBER ONE PRESCRIBED
TESTOSTERONE
REPLACEMENT THERAPY.
IT RAISES YOUR TESTOSTERONE
LEVELS, AND...
IS CONCENTRATED,
SO YOU COULD USE LESS GEL.
AND WITH AndroGel 1.62%,
YOU CAN SAVE
ON YOUR MONTHLY PRESCRIPTION.
[ Male Announcer ]
DOSING AND APPLICATION SITES
BETWEEN THESE PRODUCTS DIFFER.
WOMEN AND CHILDREN SHOULD AVOID
CONTACT WITH APPLICATION SITES.
DISCONTINUE AndroGel
AND CALL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU SEE UNEXPECTED SIGNS
OF EARLY PUBERTY IN A CHILD,
OR, SIGNS IN A WOMAN
WHICH MAY INCLUDE
CHANGES IN BODY HAIR
OR A LARGE INCREASE IN ACNE,
POSSIBLY DUE TO
ACCIDENTAL EXPOSURE.
MEN WITH BREAST CANCER
OR WHO HAVE OR MIGHT HAVE
PROSTATE CANCER,
AND WOMEN WHO ARE,
OR MAY BECOME PREGNANT
OR ARE BREAST FEEDING
SHOULD NOT USE AndroGel.
SERIOUS SIDE EFFECTS
INCLUDE WORSENING
OF AN ENLARGED PROSTATE,
POSSIBLE INCREASED RISK
OF PROSTATE CANCER,
LOWER SPERM COUNT,
SWELLING OF ANKLES, FEET,
OR BODY,
ENLARGED OR PAINFUL BREASTS,
PROBLEMS BREATHING
DURING SLEEP,
AND BLOOD CLOTS IN THE LEGS.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT YOUR MEDICAL CONDITIONS
AND MEDICATIONS,
ESPECIALLY INSULIN,
CORTICOSTEROIDS, OR MEDICINES
TO DECREASE BLOOD CLOTTING.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR TODAY
ABOUT AndroGel 1.62%
SO YOU CAN USE LESS GEL.
LOG ON NOW
TO AndroGelOffer.com
AND YOU COULD PAY AS LITTLE
AS TEN DOLLARS A MONTH
FOR AndroGel 1.62%.
WHAT ARE YOU WAITING FOR?
THIS IS BIG NEWS.
>>> U.S. STOCK FUTURES ARE UP
THIS MORNING.
MARKETS ENDED SHARPLY HIGHER
YESTERDAY ON ALL OPTIMISM THAT A
FISCAL CLIFF DEAL COULD COME BY
THE END OF THE YEAR.
CHRISTINE ROMANS IS HERE RIGHT
NOW MINDING OUR BUSINESS THIS
MORNING.
SHE'S LOOKING AT SOME OF THE
FALLOUT IN THE GUN INDUSTRY IN
THE WAKE OF THESE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL SHOOTINGS.
>> INTERESTING STORY BREAKING
THIS MORNING.
CERBERUS CAPITAL MANAGEMENT, A
PRIVATE EQUITY FIRM, MAKING
DIRECT INVESTMENTS IN COMPANIES,
INVESTORS DO, YOU HAVE TEACHERS,
PENSION FUNDS INVEST IN PRIVATE
EQUITY.
LISTEN CAREFULLY.
CERBERUS OWNS FREEDOM GROUP.
WHICH OWNS BUSHMASTER, THE
COMPANY THAT MADE THE ASSAULT
RIFLE THAT POLICE SAY WAS USED
TO KILL ALL OF THOSE CHILDREN
AND SIX TEACHERS.
THIS MORNING, CERBERUS CAPITAL
MANAGEMENT IS SAYING IT WILL
HIRE SOMEONE TO TRY TO SELL ITS
FREEDOM GROUP COMPANY, TO SELL
BUSHMASTER, TO SELL THE COMPANY
THAT MADE THAT RIFLE.
THIS IS WHAT THEY SAY BASICALLY.
IT IS APPARENT THAT THE SANDY
HOOK TRAGEDY WAS A WATERSHED
EVENT THAT HAS RAISED THE
NATIONAL DEBATE ON GUN CONTROL
TO AN UNPRECEDENTED LEVEL.
IT IS NOT OUR ROLE TO TAKE
POSITIONS OR ATTEMPT TO SHAPE OR
INFLUENCE THE GUN CONTROL POLICY
DEBATE.
THERE ARE ACTIONS THAT WE AS A
FIRM CAN TAKE.
HERE'S ONE REASON WHY PRIVATE
EQUITY MIGHT BE TAKING A STAND.
IT'S QUITE RARE REALLY FOR
PRIVATE EQUITY -- AFTER A NEWS
EVENT FOR A COMPANY TO STAY TO
SELL ITS STAKE IN WHAT IS A
CONTROVERSIAL PRODUCT.
BECAUSE TEACHERS, THE CALIFORNIA
TEACHERS RETIREMENT FUND IS
INVESTED IN CERBERUS
INVESTMENTS.
FOLLOW THIS FOR ME.
CALIFORNIA TEACHERS INVESTED IN
A PRIVATE EQUITY FUND THAT
INVESTS IN THE COMPANY THAT
MAKES GUNS.
GUNS THAT KILLED TEACHERS.
YOU CAN SEE THAT BEING
DIFFICULT.
>> EVERYONE SAYS IS THIS A
TURNING POINT IN GUN DEBATE?
IF YOU'RE SEEING BIG MONEY
DECIDE THAT IT'S A BAD
INVESTMENT TO BE INVOLVED WITH
CERTAIN GUN MANUFACTURERS,
THAT'S A BIG DEVELOPMENT.
>> UNTIL NOW, PRIVATE EQUITY
INVESTORS AND OTHERS HAVE
WEATHERED CONTROVERSY ABOUT GUN
CONTROL.
BUT THERE'S A DIFFERENT FEELING
THIS TIME.
I MEAN, YOU'RE TALKING VERY
SPECIFICALLY ABOUT A PRODUCT
THAT KILLED CHILDREN AND A LOT
OF PEOPLE ARE TALKING ABOUT
THAT.
YOU'LL HAVE 20 SOME FUNERALS
THIS WEEK AND YOU'RE GOING TO
KEEP HEARING THE WORDS
BUSHMASTER .223.
DICK'S SPORTING GOODS SAYS IT
WILL STOP SELLING SOME AUTOMATIC
RIFLES OUT OF THEIR STORES AND
THEY'RE TAKING ALL OF THE GUNS
OUT OF THEIR STORE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH,
CHRISTINE ROMANS.
>>> OTHER NEWS, JAMES CLAPPER IS
TAKING ON AS DIRECTOR OF
NATIONAL INTELLIGENCE.
CNN LEARNED THE PRESIDENT HAS
ASKED HIM TO STAY IN THE
POSITION AND HE AGREED TO REMAIN
FOR THE FORESEEABLE FUTURE.
CLAPPER HAS TAKEN HEAT FROM
REPUBLICANS FOR THE
ADMINISTRATI
ADMINISTRATION'S RESPONSE TO THE
SEPTEMBER 11th ATTACK ON THE
U.S. MISSION IN BENGHAZI.
>>> FEDEX GROUNDED HUNDREDS OF
PACKAGES NEVER MADE IT TO THEIR
NEBRASKA DESTINATIONS.
POSTAL INSPECTORS SAY A DELIVERY
DRIVER WORKING AS A PRIVATE
CONTRACTOR FOR FEDEX WAS SPOTTED
DUMPING PACKAGES FROM HIS TRUCK
ON TO THE STREET LAST MONTH.
ONLY ABOUT 30 OF THE MORE THAN
400 PACKAGES WERE FOUND INTACT
AND FINALLY DELIVERED.
THE DRIVER WAS FIRED.
YEAH, I'LL BET.
THE NEW YORK METS THEY'VE
EXPORTED CY YOUNG AWARD WINNER
R.A. DICKEY.
HE TRADED TO THE TORONTO BLUE
JAYS IN A SEVEN PLAYER DEAL THAT
WILL SEND ONE OF BASEBALL'S TOP
CATCHING PROSPECTS BACK TO NEW
YORK.
DICKEY, A 38-YEAR-OLD
KNUCKLEBALLER, A GREAT GUY WHO
THROWS A FANTASTIC PITCH, HE WAS
ON BASEBALL'S SCRAP HEAP AND
THEN HE BECAME THE KING OF THE
HILL LAST YEAR, WINNING THE CY
YOUNG, GOING 20-6 FOR THE NEW
YORK METS.
>>> MEANWHILE, HE HAD SERVED IN
HAWAII SINCE THE DAY IT BECAME A
STATE IN 1959.
THIS MORNING, TRIBUTES ARE
POURING IN FOR SENATOR DANIELLE
INOUYE.
HE WAS A VETERAN OF WORLD WAR
II, HE LOST AN ARM CHARGING
MACHINE GUN NESTS IN ITALY.
THAT SERVICE EARNED HIM THE
MEDAL OF HONOR.
HE WITNESSED THE BOMBING OF
PEARL HARBOR AS A HIGH SCHOOL
STUDENT.
DANIEL INOUYE, A HERO PRO
PROVIDED GREAT SERVICE OVER A
LONG TIME.
>>> A REPORT WILL BE DELIVERED
TO CONGRESS AS EARLY AS TODAY.
JUST AHEAD OF CONGRESSIONAL
HEARINGS THIS WEEK, THE REPORT
WAS ORDERED BY SECRETARY OF
STATE HILLARY CLINTON ALTHOUGH
SHE WILL NOT TESTIFY DUE TO THAT
ILLNESS.
SHE HAD A CONCUSSION.
SHE'S RECOVERING RIGHT NOW.
THE ATTACK BACK IN SEPTEMBER IN
BENGHAZI, KILLED FOUR AMERICANS,
INCLUDING CHRISTOPHER STEVENS,
THE U.S. AMBASSADOR TO LIBYA.
>>> IT GIVES ONE MAN SPECIAL
INSIGHT INTO BOTH AURORA AND THE
NEWTOWN SHOOTING TRAGEDIES.
HIS CLOSE CONNECTION TO BOTH
EVENTS, COMING UP.
CONCENTRATED BROTH
TO ADD DELICIOUS FLAVOR
TO YOUR SKILLET DISH
IN JUST ONE STIR.
MMM!
[ Female Announcer ]
COOK, MEET COMPLIMENTS.
GET RECIPES AT FLAVORBOOST.COM.
[ Female Announcer ]
It's hard to see opportunity
in today's challenging
environment.
Unless you have the right
perspective.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
has the vision
and experience to look beyond
the obvious.
We'll uncover opportunities,
find hidden risk,
and make success a reality.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
WHEN I'M OUT WITH MY KIDS, MY
DAUGHTER'S LIKE, "MOM, WAIT UP!"
AND I'M THINKING, "SHOULDN'T YOU
HAVE MORE ENERGY THAN ME?
YOU'RE, LIKE, EIGHT!"
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR EVERY 2 POUNDS YOU LOSE
THROUGH DIET AND EXERCISE
ALLI CAN HELP YOU LOSE
ONE MORE
BY BLOCKING SOME OF THE FAT
YOU EAT.
SIMPLE. EFFECTIVE.
ADVANTAGE: MOM.
LET'S FIGHT FAT WITH ALLI.
HAVE A HEALTHIER HOLIDAY
AT LETSFIGHTHOLIDAYFAT.COM.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME FOR CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO "EARLY
START."
WE'RE LIVE FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
IT IS AN EMOTIONAL AND DIFFICULT
DAY HERE WITH SOME CHILDREN
HEADING BACK TO SCHOOL THIS
MORNING.
THE MOTHER OF NOAH POZNER, HAS
RELEASE THE EULOGY SHE GAVE
YESTERDAY BEFORE SHE BURIED HER
LITTLE MAN.
SOME OF IT WAS PUBLISHED IN "THE
NEW YORK TIMES."
WE WANT TO SHARE SOME OF THE
TOUCHING WORDS WITH YOU THIS
MORNING.
HERE THEY ARE.
THE SKY IS CRYING AND THE FLAGS
ARE AT HALF MAST.
IT IS A SAD, SAD DAY BUT IT IS
ALSO YOUR DAY, NOAH, MY LITTLE
MAN.
I WILL MISS YOUR FORCEFUL AND
PURPOSEFUL LITTLE STEPS,
STOMPING THROUGH OUR HOUSE.
I WILL MISS YOUR PERPETUAL
SMILE, THE TWINKLE IN YOUR DARK
BLUE EYES, FRAMED BY EYELASHES
THAT WOULD BE THE ENVY OF ANY
LADY IN THIS ROOM.
SHE GOES ON TO SAY, YOUR MELODY
WILL LINGER IN OUR HEARTS
FOREVER.
MOMMA LOVES YOU, LITTLE MAN.
OUR CONDOLENCES TO THE POZNER
FAMILY.
>>> THE POST WENT VIRAL, IN IT
LIZA LONG SAYS HER AIM WAS TO
DESCRIBE THE CHALLENGE OF
RAISING A CHILD WHO SHE SAYS IS
SERIOUSLY DISTURBED.
THE BLOG POST WAS A CRY FOR
HELP.
LONG SPOKE LAST NIGHT TO CNN'S
ERIN BURNETT.
>> SOMETIMES FOR NO APPARENT
REASON HE WILL JUST TURN INTO
THIS ABSOLUTE RAGING -- I DON'T
KNOW HOW TO DESCRIBE IT.
YOU'D HAVE TO SEE IT TO BELIEVE
IT.
I STOPPED AND SAID TO MYSELF,
YOU KNOW, THIS ISN'T NORMAL.
I HAVE TO FACE UP TO THE FACT
THAT I HAVE A SICK SON AND WE
NEED HELP.
>> LIES DA TELLING CNN SHE LOVES
HER SON BUT HE, QUOTE, TERRIFIES
ME.
FOR ONE CONNECTICUT MAN, IT IS
HARD FOR HIM TO BELIEVE WHAT HAS
HAPPENED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
STEVEN BARTON HAS BEEN THROUGH A
MASS SHOOTING BEFORE.
HE WAS SERIOUSLY WOUNDED IN THE
SHOOTING AT THE MOVIE THEATER IN
AURORA, COLORADO, BACK IN JULY
AS YOU RECALL.
LIKE SO MANY, HIS HEART BREAKS
FOR ALL OF THE VICTIMS.
BUT UNLIKE OTHERS HE KNOWS THE
VIOLENCE AND FEAR FIRSTHAND.
>> OUR COUNTRY IS LONG OVERDUE
FOR A SERIOUS DISCUSSION ABOUT
GUNS, ABOUT MENTAL HEALTH.
YOU'LL MAKE IT A LOT HARDER FOR
CRIMINALS TO GET ILLEGAL GUNS.
>> BARTON WORKS FOR AN
ORGANIZATION DEVOTED TO
PREVENTING GUN VIOLENCE.
>>> THE POSTAL SERVICE HAS
ESTABLISHED A POST OFFICE BOX
FOR ANYONE ANYWHERE WHO WANTS TO
REACH OUT TO THE PEOPLE OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
HERE IT IS FOR YOU.
MESSAGE OF CONDOLENCE CAN BE
SENT TO P.O. BOX 3700, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
ZIP IS 06470.
IT'S THERE ON THE SCREEN FOR YOU
TO READ AS WELL.
WE HAVE ANOTHER TUNE FOR YOU TO
HELP, TO FIND OUT HOW YOU CAN
HELP THOSE THAT WERE AFFECTED BY
THIS TRAGEDY, GO TO
CNN.COM/IMPACT.
THERE ARE A LOT OF OPTIONS FOR
YOU THERE.
SO MANY PEOPLE ACROSS THE
COUNTRY WHO REALLY WANT TO
FIGURE OUT A WAY TO HELP.
THAT'S A REALLY GOOD OPTION FOR
YOU.
>>> AMID SHIFT IN PUBLIC OPINION
IN THE WAKE OF THE NEWTOWN
TRAGEDY.
HE IS STICKING TO HIS GUNS.
YOU'LL HEAR FROM TEXAS GOVERNOR
RICK PERRY.
THAT'S COMING UP.
YOU KNOW HOW TO MIX BUSINESS...
WITH BUSINESS.
AND YOU...RENT FROM NATIONAL.
BECAUSE ONLY NATIONAL LETS YOU
CHOOSE ANY CAR IN THE AISLE.
AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE A FULL-SIZE
OR ABOVE.
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
I COULD GET USED TO THIS.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, YOU COULD BUSINESS PRO.
YES, YOU COULD.
GO NATIONAL. GO LIKE A PRO.
MAKE A WISH!
I WISH WE COULD
LIE HERE FOREVER.
I WISH THIS TEST DRIVE WAS OVER,
SO WE COULD HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
TEST DRIVE!
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A JETTA.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN,
$0 DUE AT SIGNING, $0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
>>> TWO-WEEK WARNING UNTIL THE
FISCAL CLIFF AND A ONE-ON-ONE
MEETING AT THE WHITE HOUSE
RESULTS IN MAJOR MOVEMENT
TOWARDS A DEAL.
>>> THE TIDE COULD BE TURNING IN
THE GUN CONTROL DEBATE.
A MAJOR CORPORATION AND EVEN
SOME REPUBLICANS SHOWING SEENS
OF CHANGE.
>>> AN ANXIOUS MORNING IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
MANY STUDENTS AND PARENTS HERE
PUTTING THEIR FEAR ASIDE AND
HEADING BACK TO SCHOOL THIS
MORNING.
WELCOME BACK TO "EARLY START,"
I'M ZORAIDA SAMBOLIN.
I WILL HAVE MUCH MORE LIVE FROM
NEWTOWN, COMING UP.
>> I'M JOHN BERMAN HERE IN NEW
YORK.
IT'S 31 MINUTES AFTER THE HOUR
RIGHT NOW.
WE DO HAVE BIG NEWS COMING OUT
OF WASHINGTON ON THE FISCAL
CLIFF NEGOTIATION.
IT'S ABOUT TIME, WITH JUST 14
DAYS TO GO NOW, WE LEARNED
OVERNIGHT THAT PRESIDENT OBAMA
GAVE SERIOUS GROUND IN HIS
LATEST PROPOSAL TO HOUSE SPEAKER
JOHN BOEHNER.
TAX RATES WOULD RISE ON INCOMES
OVER $400,000.
PREVIOUSLY THE PRESIDENT WANTED
HIGHER TAXES ON HOUSE HOLES
STARTING AT $250,000.
THE PRESIDENT IS ALSO OFFERING
NEW SPENDING CUTS WORTH AROUND
$200 BILLION.
THE SPEAKER HAS GIVEN SOME
GROUND HIMSELF GOING FROM A NO
NEW TAXES POSITION TO PROPOSING
TAX HIKES ON THOSE MAKING $1
MILLION.
TODAY THE HOUSE SPEAKER MEETS
WITH SOME REPUBLICAN HOUSE
MEMBERS TO UPDATE THEM ON THE
NEGOTIATIONS.
THIS COULD BE A PRICKLY MEETING.
DAN LOTHIAN IS IN WASHINGTON.
IT DOES LOOK LIKE THERE'S SOME
MOVEMENT.
>> Reporter: IT DOES.
EVEN HOUSE REPUBLICAN AIDES ARE
SAYING THIS IS POSITIVE
MOVEMENT, BUT THEY STILL TAKE
ISSUE WITH THE PRESIDENT'S MATH.
NONETHELESS, WHAT WE HAVE SEEN
HERE IS A BIG BREAKTHROUGH
BECAUSE THE PRESIDENT OVER THE
CAMPAIGN TRAIL YEARS WHEN THE
PRESIDENT WAS OUT THERE PUSHING
THIS MIDDLE CLASS TAX CUT TO
VOTERS, THE PRESIDENT WAS
INSISTENT THAT HE DID NOT WANT
TAXES TO GO UP ON THOSE MAKING
UP TO 250,000 BUT THOSE ABOVE
THAT, TAXES SHOULD GO UP ON
THEM, THE BUSH ERA TAX CUTS
SHOULD EXPIRE FOR THEM.
NOW THE PRESIDENT RAISING THAT
CEILING TO $400,000.
SO THAT IS A DRAMATIC
DEVELOPMENT.
YOU KNOW, FOR THE MOST PART,
MUCH OF THE NEGOTIATIONS HAVE
TAKEN PLACE BEHIND THE SCENES.
AND IN FACT WE OFTEN DON'T FIND
OUT THAT THE TWO LEADERS HAVE
SPOKEN EITHER BY PHONE OR FACE
TO FACE UNTIL AFTER THOSE
MEETINGS HAVE TAKEN PLACE.
AND THAT WAS THE CASE YESTERDAY.
CERTAINLY WE DID NOT FIND OUT
THAT THE PRESIDENT WAS MEETING
WITH SPEAKER BOEHNER UNTIL ABOUT
20 MINUTES OR SO BEFORE THAT
MEETING WAS OVER.
THEY MET FOR 45 MINUTES AT THE
WHITE HOUSE.
THAT WAS THE THIRD TIME THAT
THEY HAD MET FACE TO FACE OVER
THE LAST EIGHT DAYS.
AND SO, AGAIN, IT DOES SHOW THAT
THEY ARE MAKING SOME BIG
MOVEMENTS, SOME BIG CONCESSIONS
HERE.
IT WILL BE INTEREST TO SEE IF IT
TENS OVER THE NEXT FEW HOURS.
>> INTERESTING THAT WE'RE SEEING
SO MANY OF THE NUMBERS FROM
THESE DISCUSSIONS.
THE PRESIDENT OFFERING THE TAX
RATE HIKE AT $400,000, SPEAKER
BOEHNER AT $1 MILLION RIGHT NOW.
HOW MUCH HOPE IS THERE THAT
THEY'LL REACH SOME KIND OF DEAL
BEFORE JANUARY 1st?
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU KNOW, THE INTERESTING THING
IS AS THESE NUMBERS HAVE GONE
UP, YOU SEE SPEAKER BOEHNER
TALKING ABOUT RAISING, AS YOU
POINTED OUT, THE TAXES ON THOSE
MILLION DOLLAR THRESHOLD, THE
PRESIDENT 400,000.
THAT ANGERS THE LEFT OF THE
PRESIDENT'S PARTY AND FOR
SPEAKER BOEHNER, IT ANGERS THE
RIGHT IN HIS PARTY.
AND SO THOSE ISSUES STILL HAVE
TO BE RESOLVED BUT I THINK
THERE'S OPTIMISM AS SPEAKER
BOEHNER WILL GO BACK AND TALK TO
HIS FOLKS, PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL
CONTINUE TO PROD THOSE IN HIS
PARTY.
BOTH SIDES REALIZE IT'S URGENT
THAT THERE HAVE TO BE SOME
CONCESSIONS IN ORDER TO GET THIS
DEAL DONE BY THE END OF THE
YEAR.
WHEN YOU SEE SUCH BIG MOVEMENT
LIKE YOU'VE SEEN OVER THE LAST
COUPLE OF DAYS, THERE'S MORE
OPTIMISM THIS WILL GET DONE IN
TIME.
>> THAT IS TRUE.
THEY BOTH DID COME OFF THEIR
INITIAL BARGAINING POSITIONS BY
A LOT.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> DAN LOTHIAN, THANKS VERY MUCH
THIS MORNING.
>> OKAY.
>>> ZORAIDA IS IN NEWTOWN.
WE GO BACK TO CONNECTICUT.
>> AS NEWTOWN PREPARES TO BURY
ANOTHER 6-YEAR-OLD CHILD TODAY,
THERE ARE KEY DEVELOPMENTS TO
REPORT IN THE NATIONAL GUN
CONTROL DEBATE.
HERE'S THE VERY LATEST FOR YOU.
FOUR DAYS AFTER THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL MASSACRE,
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS TAKING
ACTION.
"THE WASHINGTON POST" REPORTS
THAT HE HAS ORDERED HIS CABINET
TO PUT TOGETHER PROPOSALS THAT
INCLUDE REINSTATING A BAN ON
ASSAULT RIFLES.
VICE PRESIDENT BIDEN HAS BEEN
ASKED TO LEAD THE CHARGE ON THAT
EFFORT.
DICK'S SPORTING GOODS ANNOUNCING
IT HAS REMOVED ALL GUNS FROM ITS
STORE CLOSEST TO NEWTOWN.
AND ALSO SUSPENDING SALES OF ALL
MODERN SPORTING RIFLES.
THIS IS HAPPENING CHAINWIDE.
OUT OF RESPECT FOR THE VICTIMS
OF THE SCHOOL SHOOTING.
>>> AND 3450E7B WHILE, GRIEF
COUNSELORS AND POLICE WILLING ON
HAND THIS MORNING WHEN ALL KIDS
ALL OVER NEWTOWN HEAD BACK TO
CLASS FOR FIRST TIME SINCE
FRIDAY.
THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
WILL REMAIN CLOSED.
I WANT TO TELL YOU ABOUT JESSICA
REKOS.
SHE WILL BE LAID TO REST TODAY.
THIS LITTLE 6-YEAR-OLD GIRL
ADORED HORSES, COULDN'T WAIT
UNTIL HER 10th BIRTHDAY TO GET
ONE.
THAT'S WHAT HER FAMILY PROMISED
HER.
I WANT TO SHARE MORE ABOUT HER,
BECAUSE JUST A SPECTACULAR
LITTLE GIRL.
HER FAMILY SAYS SHE WAS THE CEO
OF THE FAMILY.
SHE WAS THE FIRST ONE TO PLAN
EVERYTHING INCREDIBLY ORGANIZED.
SHE WAS A BALL OF FIRE.
SHE RULED THE ROOST.
YOU KNOW, THIS LITTLE GIRL LOVED
TO WRITE.
SHE LEFT NOTES ALL OVER THE
HOUSE.
HER MOM SAYS THAT SHE FOUND A
JOURNAL AND IT WAS EXACTLY WHAT
SHE NEEDED, BECAUSE IT SAID I
LOVE YOU SO MUCH MOMMA, LOVE
JESSICA.
YOU KNOW, SHE SAID THEY'RE STILL
FINDING NOTES ALL OVER THE HOUSE
THAT THIS LITTLE GIRL LEFT
BEHIND AND THAT IT'S HELPED THEM
WITH THE HEALING PROCESS.
THEY ARE COMMITTED TO KEEP THIS
LITTLE GIRL'S MEMORY ALIVE.
MEANWHILE, PEOPLE IN NEWTOWN ARE
COMING TOGETHER, PRESSING ON AS
THEY CONTINUE TO GRIEVE.
THE FORMER CHAIRWOMAN OF
NEWTOWN'S BOARD OF EDUCATION
TELLING OUR WOLF BLITZER THAT
SHE FEELS HOLLOW.
>> IT'S BEEN HORRIFIC.
FROM THE MOMENT WE ALL HEARD THE
NEWS, IT WAS DEVASTATING TO KNOW
THAT SOMEONE HAD COME INTO THE
SCHOOL WITH A GUN.
THAT ALONE WAS HORRIBLE ENOUGH,
BECAUSE IT'S A PLACE OF PEACE
AND JOY.
BUT NOW AS WE GO FORWARD AND
WE'VE LEARNED THE NAMES AND NOW
WE'RE GOING THROUGH THE
GRUELLING PROCESS OF THE
FUNERALS, IT'S VERY, VERY, VERY
HARD.
EVERYONE USES THE WORD HOLLOW.
THAT'S WHERE WE'RE AT RIGHT NOW.
>> AND THIS MORNING, IT IS A BIG
STEP IN THE RECOVERY PROCESS FOR
NEWTOWN STUDENTS AND, OF COURSE,
FOR THEIR FAMILIES.
THEY ARE ALL HEADED BACK TO
SCHOOL THIS MORNING.
SANDRA ENDOIS FOLLOWING THE
RETURN TO THE CLASSROOM.
I WOULD IMAGINE THIS WILL BE A
DIFFICULT TIME FOR THE PARENTS
AS WELL AS THE KIDS.
>> Reporter: ABSOLUTELY,
ZORAIDA.
CERTAINLY SOME ANXIETY THIS
MORNING AS STUDENTS START
RETURNING BACK TO SCHOOL BUT
THIS IS A FIRST STEP TOWARDS
NORMALCY IN THE WAKE OF THIS
TRAGEDY.
ROUGHLY 5,400 NEWTOWN DISTRICT
STUDENTS WILL BE ABLE TO RETURN
TO CLASS TODAY.
THERE WILL BE A TWO-HOUR DELAY.
THIS APPLIES TO ALL STUDENTS
EXCEPT FOR SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
STUDENTS.
CLASSES THERE ARE STILL
SUSPENDED.
WE KNOW THAT THERE WILL BE A
TWO-HOUR DELAY WS ALSO GRIEF
COUNSELORS AND POLICE WILL BE
PRESENT AT NEWTOWN SCHOOLS TODAY
AND THROUGHOUT THE WEEK.
INTERESTING TO NOTE, PRINCIPALS
HAVE ASKED PARENTS TO TALK TO
THEIR CHILDREN ABOUT THE
INCIDENT BEFORE THEY HEAD BACK
INTO THE CLASSROOMS.
THAT'S BECAUSE THEY CAN'T
CONTROL WHAT OTHER STUDENTS MAY
BE SAYING INSIDE SCHOOL AND THEY
DON'T WANT THEM TO LEARN ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED FROM OTHER
STUDENTS.
AND IN AN UNCONTROLLED
ENVIRONMENT.
AND, OF COURSE, ZORAIDA,
TEACHERS WILL BE ADDRESSING WHAT
HAPPENED IN AN AGE-APPROPRIATE
MANNER.
>> ALL RIGHT, SANDRA ENDO LIVE
FOR US.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WE SEND IT BACK TO JOHN BERMAN.
HE'S IN NEW YORK.
>> THANKS, ZORAIDA.
>>> NEW THIS MORNING, DICK'S
SPORTING GOODS TAKING ACTION IN
THE WAKE OF MASSACRE IN NEWTOWN.
THE COMPANY RELEASE THIS
STATEMENT, THEY SAY OUT OF
RESPECT FOR THE VICTIMS AND
THEIR FAMILIES, WE'VE REMOVED
ALL GUNS IN OUR STORE NEAREST TO
NEWTOWN AND SUSPENDED THE SALE
OF MODERN SPORTING RIFLES IN ALL
OF OUR STORES CHAINWIDE.
>>> MORE FALLOUT, A COMPANY
CALLED CERBERUS CAPITAL MGT THE
ANNOUNCING ITS SELLING ITS FNT
STAKE IN FREEDOM GROUP WHICH
AREQUIRED BUSHMASTER, THE
COMPANY THAT MANUFACTURED THE
AR-15 MODEL USED IN FRIDAY'S
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
>>> IT DIDN'T TAKE LONG FOR
PRESIDENT OBAMA TO TAKE ACTION.
"THE WASHINGTON POST" REPORTING
HE'S DIRECTED MEMBERS OF HIS
CABINET TO PUT TOGETHER A LIST
OF PROPOSALS THAT INCLUDES
REINSTATING A BAN ON ASSAULT
RIFLES.
THIS EFFORT IS BEING LED BY VICE
PRESIDENT JOE BIDEN.
>>> AND THE WHITE HOUSE APPEARS
TO HAVE SOME MOMENTUM HERE.
TWO INFLUENTIAL DEMOCRATIC
SENATORS WITH "A" RATINGS WITH
THE NRA, MARK WARNER OF VIRGINIA
AND JOE MANCHIN OF WEST VIRGINIA
ARE SOUNDING PRETTY READY TO
RECONSIDER THEIR POSITIONS.
>> WHO WOULD HAVE EVER THOUGHT
IN AMERICA OR ANYWHERE IN THE
WORLD THAT CHILDREN WOULD BE
SLAUGHTERED?
YOU KNOW, IT'S CHANGED ME.
I DON'T KNOW OF ANYBODY THAT
GOES HUNTING WITH AN ASSAULT
RIFLE.
I DON'T KNOW PEOPLE THAT NEED
10, 20, 30-ROUND CLIPS.
>> I BELIEVE EVERY AMERICAN HAS
SECOND AMENDMENT RIGHTS AND THAT
THE ABILITY TO HUNT IS PART OF
OUR CULTURE.
I HAD AN NRA RATING OF AN "A."
BUT YOU KNOW, ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
>> AGAIN, THESE ARE TWO PRO-GUN
DEMOCRATS.
BIG MOVEMENT FROM THEM ON THIS
ISSUE.
MORE AND MORE AMERICANS SEEM TO
BE GETTING ON BOARD WITH THE
IDEA OF TIGHTER GUN CONTROL LAWS
IN THIS COUNTRY.
A NEW CBS NEWS POLL SHOWS 57%
NOW BELIEVE WE NEED STRICTER GUN
LAWS.
THAT'S AN INCREASE OF 18% SINCE
APRIL.
ONE GUY, THOUGH, WHO DOESN'T
SEEM TO AGREE, TEXAS GOVERNOR
RICK PERRY, HE IS STICKING TO
HIS GUNS SO TO SPEAK.
AT A STATE TEA PARTY FORUM LAST
NIGHT, PERRY TOOK ISSUE WITH
CALLS FOR STRICTER GUN CONTROL
LAWS FOLLOWING THE NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT MASSACRE.
>> IN THE STATE OF TEXAS WITH
OUR CONCEALED HANDGUN LICENSE,
IF YOU GO THROUGH THE PROCESS
AND YOU HAVE BEEN DULY
BACKGROUNDED AND TRAINED AND YOU
ARE A CONCEALED HANDGUN LICENSE
CARRYING INDIVIDUAL, YOU SHOULD
BE ABLE TO CARRY YOUR HANDGUN
ANYWHERE IN THIS STATE.
>> PERRY SAYS WE NEED TO MAKE
SCHOOLS SAFER.
IF THAT MEANS ARMING TEACHERS
AND ADMINISTRATORS, HE SAYS HE'S
FINE WITH THAT.
LAWMAKERS NEED TO ADDRESS MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES AS WELL.
>>> GAMERFITNATION.COM IS
CALLING FOR A SHOW OF SUPPORT
FOR THE FAMILIES IN THE NEWTOWN
MASSACRE.
IT'S ASKING ALL GAMERS TO JOIN
IN WHAT IT CALLS A DAY OF
CEASE-FIRE ON FRIDAY, DECEMBER
21st.
>>> GOVERNOR NIKKI HALEY SAYS
SHE CHOSE SCOTT, HE'S ON THE
RIGHT OF YOUR SCREEN, BECAUSE OF
HIS BACKGROUND IN BUSINESS ALONG
WITH HIS COMMITMENT TO WHAT SHE
CALLS CONSERVATIVE PRINCIPLES.
SCOTT WILL BE ONLY
AFRICAN-AMERICAN IN THE SENATE
WHEN HE'S SWORN IN.
SENATOR JIM DEMINT IS LEADING TO
HEAD UP THE HERITAGE FOUNDATION,
A CONSERVATIVE THINK TANK.
>>> THE OSCAR-WINNING DIRECTOR
SCORSESE TO DIRECT BILL CLINTON
DOCUMENTARY.
THAT SHOULD BE INTERESTING TO
SAY THE LEAST.
>>> COMING UP, A ONE-MAN TRIBUTE
TO THE VICTIMS OF THE NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT MASSACRE ON
FOOTBALL'S PRIMETIME STAGE.
SNEEZING,  EVE ,
ACHES, FEVERS.
AND I RELIEVE
NASAL CONGESTION.
OVERACHIEVER.
[ Female Announcer ] TYLENOL®
COLD MULTI-SYMPTOM NIGHTTIME
RELIEVES NASAL CONGESTION.
NYQUIL® COLD AND FLU DOESN'T.
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAND.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
YOU KNOW IT CAN BE HARD TO
LBREATHE, AND HOW THAT FEELS.E,
COPD INCLUDES CHRONIC
BRONCHITIS AND EMPHYSEMA.
SPIRIVA HELPS CONTROL
MY COPD SYMPTOMS
BY KEEPING MY AIRWAYS
OPEN FOR 24 HOURS.
PLUS, IT REDUCES COPD FLARE-UPS.
SPIRIVA IS THE ONLY ONCE-DAILY
INHALED COPD MAINTENANCE
TREATMENT THAT DOES BOTH.
SPIRIVA HANDIHALER TIOTROPIUM
BROMIDE INHALATION POWDER
DOES NOT REPLACE FAST-ACTING
INHALERS FOR SUDDEN SYMPTOMS.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU HAVE
KIDNEY PROBLEMS, GLAUCOMA,
TROUBLE URINATING, OR
AN ENLARGED PROSTATE.
THESE MAY WORSEN WITH SPIRIVA.
DISCUSS ALL MEDICINES
YOU TAKE, EVEN EYE DROPS.
STOP TAKING SPIRIVA AND SEEK
IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
IF YOUR BREATHING
SUDDENLY WORSENS,
YOUR THROAT OR TONGUE
SWELLS, YOU GET HIVES,
VISION CHANGES OR EYE PAIN,
OR PROBLEMS PASSING URINE.
OTHER SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE
DRY MOUTH AND CONSTIPATION.
NOTHING CAN REVERSE COPD.
SPIRIVA HELPS ME BREATHE BETTER.
(BLOWING SOUND)
ASK YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT SPIRIVA.
Your soups are
so awesomely delicious
my husband and I
can't stop eating 'em!
What's...that...
on your head?
Can curlers!
Tomato Basil,
Potato with bacon...
we've got a lot of empty cans.
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
>>> WELCOME BACK.
IT IS 45 MINUTES PAST THE HOUR.
LET'S GET YOU UP TO DATE WITH
THIS MORNING'S TOP STORIES.
>>> FOR THE FIRST TIME SINCE
FRIDAY, CHILDREN IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT WILL BE HEADING BACK
TO SCHOOL TODAY.
THERE WILL BE COUNSELORS ON HAND
AS WELL AS INCREASED POLICE
PATROLS.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY, HOWEVER,
REMAINS CLOSED.
>>> AND WE HAVE NEW INFORMATION
THIS MORNING ABOUT THE NEWTOWN
SHOOTER AB ADAM LANZA.
THE BUREAU OF ALCOHOL, TOBACCO
AND FIREARMS CONFIRMS THAT HE
DID VISIT A GUN RANGE WITH HIS
MOTHER AS RECENTLY AS SIX MONTHS
AGO.
AND A TECHNOLOGY ADVISER FROM
NEWTOWN HIGH SCHOOL SAYS THEY
WERE BEING VERY CAREFUL WITH
LANZA BECAUSE IF HE HURT HIMSELF
OR CUT HIMSELF, THAT HE COULD
NOT FEEL THE PAIN.
>>> MEANTIME, POLICE IN
FAIRFIELD, CALIFORNIA ARRESTING
A MAN FOR ALLEGEDLY THREATEN TO
DUPLICATE THE NEWTOWN SHOOTING.
HE'S ACCUSED OF POSTING COMMENTS
ONLINE INDICATING THAT HE
SUPPORTED THE ACTIONS OF THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTER AND
THOUGHT OF POSSIBLY COMMITTING
SIMILAR ACTS.
THERE'S A PICTURE OF HIM.
POLICE SAY THEY SEIZED SEVERAL
ITEMS IN A SEARCH OF HIS HOME.
>>> AND THE TITANS STAR RUNNING
BACK CHRIS JOHNSON PAYING
TRIBUTE TO ALL 26 VICTIMS OF THE
NEWTOWN TRAGEDY.
ON HIS CLEATS DURING "MONDAY
NIGHT FOOTBALL," TAKE A LOOK AT
THAT THERE, HE BROKE OFF A
94-YARD TOUCHDOWN RUN IN THOSE
CLEATS IN THE 14-10 WIN OVER THE
JETS.
>>> AND FOLKS TO FIND OUT HOW
YOU CAN HELP THOSE AFFECTED BY
THIS TRAGEDY AS I KNOW MANY OF
YOU WANT TO DO, GO TO
CNN.COM/IMPACT.
THERE ARE A LOT OF OPTIONS FOR
YOU THERE ON HOW TO HELP.
WE ARE SEEING WORLDWIDE SUPPORT,
JOHN.
EVERYBODY WANTS TO SEE WHAT THEY
CAN DO.
THAT'S A GOOD OPTION FOR FOLKS.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
YOU SEE CHRIS JOHNSON WITH THAT
ON HIS CLEATS.
EVERYWHERE YOU GO, EVERYONE YOU
TALK TO IS FEELING THIS TRAGEDY
IN ONE WAY OR ANOTHER.
I HAVE NEVER SEEN ANYTHING WHERE
SO MANY PEOPLE WANT TO HELP.
THEY WANT TO THE DO WHATEVER
THEY CAN.
THANKS, ZORAIDA.
>>> STORMY WEATHER IN THE WEST
AND MIDWEST COULD AFFECT YOUR
TRAVEL PLANS TODAY.
IT WAS UGLY HERE IN THE EAST,
TOO.
LET'S GET TO KAREN McAGAIN NIS
IN FOR ROB MARCIANO TODAY.
>> JOHN, YES, IT DOES LOOK LIKE
A VERY UNSETTLED WEATHER
PATTERN, NOT JUST ACROSS THE
WEST COAST AND THE EAST BUT
MIDWEST, JUST IN TIME FOR
CHRISTMAS.
IT LOOKS LIKE IF YOU ARE
TRAVELING TOWARDS THE MIDWEST,
SERIOUS SNOW EXPECTED THERE IN
THE NEXT SEVERAL DAYS.
LOOK AT THE WEST COAST AND
SEATTLE, THE SNOW LEVELS HAVE
BEEN DOWN AS LOW AS 200 FEET.
THEY WILL GO UP TO 400 FEET FOR
THE AFTERNOON.
SOME OF THESE SNOWFALL TOTALS,
VERY SUBSTANTIAL GOING INTO THE
NEXT SEVERAL DAYS.
COULD SEE 10 OR 20 INCHES OF
SNOWFALL.
BUT IN THE MIDWEST, THIS IS WHAT
WE'LL FOCUS ON.
WE HAVEN'T SEEN A SIGNIFICANT
SNOW EVENT LIKE THIS.
THIS ONE OCCURS AS WE GO INTO
WEDNESDAY AND THEN FOR THURSDAY,
SO YOU'RE TRAVELING INTO CHICAGO
OR DES MOINES OR TOPEKA, WICHITA
AND EVEN INTO DENVER.
YOU COULD EXPECT PERHAPS SOME
DELAYS LATER ON IN THE WORKWEEK.
HOW ABOUT 48-HOUR SNOWFALL
TOTALS?
SPOKANE JUST UNDER 5 INCHES
BEING REPORTED THERE.
IN LIBBY, MONTANA, TWO-DAY SNOW
TOTALS JUST ABOUT 2 FEET.
AND NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, RIGHT
NOW OVERCAST WITH RAIN.
THE TEMPERATURE A COLD RAIN.
41 DEGREES.
THE WINDS ARE OUT OF THE EAST
AND NORTHEAST BUT AS WE GO INTO
THE NEXT FIVE DAYS, WE'LL LOOK
AT A LITTLE BIT OF A BREAK
WEATHERWISE.
THOSE TEMPERATURES WILL REMAIN
IN THE 40s BUT THEN AS WE GO
INTO FRIDAY, THE RAIN IS GOING
TO RETURN AND A 20% CHANCE OF
SOME SHOWERS COMING UP FOR
SATURDAY AND TEMPERATURES
TURNING MUCH COOLER.
JOHN?
>> ALL RIGHT.
KAREN McGINNIS IN ATLANTA.
THANKS VERY MUCH.
>>> COMING UP WE'LL ADDRESS ONE
OF THE MOST DIFFICULT, TROUBLING
QUESTIONS AFTER THE NEWTOWN
MASSACRE.
WHY?
DR. GUPTA, SANJAY GUPTA GOES
INSIDE THE VIOLENT MIND FOR
ANSWERS.
DOES THE BRAIN CONTAIN CLUES
ABOUT WHY KILLERS SNAP?
challeg
environment.
Unless you have the right
perspective.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
has the vision
and experience to look beyond
the obvious.
We'll uncover opportunities,
find hidden risk,
and make success a reality.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYONE, TO
THIS SPECIAL EDITION OF "EARLY
START."
AS PEOPLE IN NEWTOWN AND AROUND
THE WORLD TRY TO MAKE SENSE OF
THE TRAGEDY THERE, THE BIGGEST
QUESTION, OF COURSE, IS WHY?
WHY DID THE SHOOTER TARGET AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL?
WHY DID HE GUN DOWN 20 6 AND
7-YEAR-OLD KIDS?
CHIEF MEDICAL CORRESPONDENT
DR. SANJAY GUPTA HAS BEEN
FOLLOWING THIS.
>> Reporter: FIRST THING YOU
NOTICE AROUND NEWTOWN, EVERYONE
HAS THAT QUESTIONING LOOK, WHY,
WHAT DID WE MISS, IF ANYTHING?
NO ANSWERS YET, JUST HINDSIGHT.
TO TRY AND MAKE SOME SENSE OF
THE TRAGEDY HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, MEDICAL
INVESTIGATORS WILL OFTEN LOOK
FOR EVIDENCES OF PATTERNS, NOT
TALKING ABOUT CLOTHING EXILES OR
MUSICAL PREFERENCES OR EVEN
LIFESTYLE BUT RATHER LOOKING FOR
EVIDENCE OF SPECIFIC PLANS,
COULD GIVE SOME CLUES AS TO WHAT
WAS HAPPENING IN A PERSON'S MIND
AND IN THEIR BRAIN.
IT'S HARD TO KNOW BECAUSE
THANKFULLY, THERE ARE RELATIVELY
FEW TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS ONE.
A CLOSE LOOK AT TEN OF THE MOST
ANALYZED MASS MURDER CASES IN
HISTORY PROVIDE REMARKABLE
INSIGHT.
ACCORDING TO THIS RESEARCH
PUBLISHED IN THE JOURNAL
"AGGRESSION AND VIOLENT
BEHAVIOR," TYPICALS START BY
PLACING THESE KILLERS INTO THREE
CATEGORIES, TRAUMATIZED,
PSYCHOTIC, PSYCHOPATHIC.
IN 2005, I 16-YEAR-OLD KILLED
NINE PEOPLE AT A SCHOOL IN
MINNESOTA.
A LOOK IN HIS PAST REVEALED AN
ABUSED BOY WITH AN AWFUL FAMILY
HISTORY.
THE SHOOTER HAD BEEN PREVIOUSLY
TRAUMATIZED.
THE VIRGINIA TECH SHOOTER KILLED
32 PEOPLE.
6 WERE MURDERED IN ARIZONA AND
12 LIVES WERE TAKEN IN AN
AURORA, COLORADO MOVIE THEATER.
IN EACH CASE, THE KILLERS SHOWED
SIGNS OF PSYCHOTIC BEHAVIOR,
SEVERE DELUSIONS AND PARANOIA.
13 PEOPLE WERE SHOT AND KILLED
IN COLUMBINE, COLORADO.
ONE OF THE MURDERS WAS LATER
DISCOVERED TO A TEXTBOOK PSYC
PSYCHOPA
PSYCHOPATH.
LOOKING BACK NONE OF THEM HAD
SNAPPED.
THEY ALL LEFT CLUES, PIECED
TOGETHER AFTER IT WAS TOO LATE.
HINDSIGHT.
>> WE STILL DON'T KNOW MUCH
ABOUT THE SHOOTER WHO LIVED IN
THIS HOME BUT THERE IS SOMETHING
ELSE TO CONSIDER.
WHAT MEDICATIONS, IF ANY, HE WAS
ON.
I'M SPECIFICALLY TALKING ABOUT
ANTIDEPRESSANTS.
IF YOU LOOK AT THE STUDIES ON
OTHER SHOOTINGS LIKE THIS THAT
HAVE HAPPENED, McS LIKE THIS
WERE A COMMON FACTOR.
NOW, I WANT TO BE CLEAR, NOT
SAYING THAT ANTIDEPRESSANTS
CAN'T BE EFFECTIVE BUT PEOPLE
SEEM TO AGREE THERE IS A
VULNERABLE TIME WHEN SOMEONE
STARTS THESE MEDICATIONS AND
WHEN SOMEONE STOPS COULD LEAD TO
INCREASED IMPULSIVITY, DECREASED
JUDGMENT AND MAKING SOMEONE OUT
OF TOUCH.
NONE OF THIS IS AN EXCUSE AND
IT'S NEVER JUST ONE THING.
NONE OF THESE BEHAVIORS WILL
FULLY PREDICT OR EXPLAIN WHY.
BUT SOON AGAIN, THERE WILL BE
HINDSIGHT THAT MIGHT JUST HELP
PREVENT ANOTHER TRAGEDY.
DR. SANJAY GUPTA, CNN, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> AND WE WILL HAVE MUCH MORE
FROM NEWTOWN NEXT HOUR.
ANOTHER VERY, VERY HARD DAY
AHEAD.
WE'RE ALSO WATCHING SOME MAJOR
DEVELOPMENTS IN THE FISCAL CLIFF
NEGOTIATIONS OUT OF WASHINGTON.
THE PRESIDENT SEEMS TO BUDGE ON
A KEY NUMBER AND WE COULD BE
MOVING CLOSER TO A DEAL.
NNING F.
FORTUNATELY WE'VE GOT INK.
IT GIVES US 5X THE REWARDS
ON OUR INTERNET, PHONE
CHARGES AND CABLE,
PLUS AT OFFICE SUPPLY STORES.
REWARDS WE PUT RIGHT
BACK INTO OUR BUSINESS.
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
WE'VE EVER WANTED TO DO
AND INK HELPS US DO IT.
MAKE YOUR MARK
WITH INK FROM CHASE.
>>> GOOD MORNING.
WELCOME, EVERYBODY.
COULD IT BE A TIPPING POINT FOR
GUN CONTROL?
I'M SOLEDAD O'BRIEN.
THE WHITE HOUSE MAJOR RETAILER,
NATIONAL POLLS, EVEN SOME PRO
GUN REPUBLICANS ARE NOW SHIFTING
IN THE WAKE OF THIS MASSACRE IN
NEWTOWN.
>>> FIRST, VERY CAUTIOUS STEP
HERE IN NEWTOWN.
I'M ZORAIDA SAMBOLIN.
MOST SCHOOL-AGED CHILDREN ARE
HEADING BACK TO SCHOOL JUST
HOURS FROM NOW.
WE'RE FOLLOWING THOSE
DEVELOPMENTS.
>>> IS IT A BREAKTHROUGH FOR
FISCAL CLIFF TALKS?
I'M JOHN BERMAN.
THE TWO SIDES ARE CLOSER THAN
EVER BEFORE WITH JUST TWO WEEKS
LEFT TO GO.
GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE.
WE'LL GO LIVE TO WASHINGTON IN
JUST A MOMENT FOR MORE ON THE
FISCAL CLIFF, COMING UP.
>>> BUT IN THE MEANTIME, WELCOME
TO A SPECIAL EDITION OF "EARLY
START."
WE'RE ALSO LIVE HERE IN LIVE IN
CONNECTICUT.
>> 6:00 IN THE MORNING IN THE
EAST COAST.
>> AND ANOTHER BEAUTIFUL YOUNG
CHILD WILL BE BURIED TODAY.
FOUR DAYS AFTER A SCHOOL
MASSACRE, THAT HAS NUMBED THE
ENTIRE NATION.
SHEER THE LA
HERE IS THE LATEST.
THIS IS REIGNITING THE GUN
CONTROL DEBATE.
THE PRESIDENT TAKING STEPS TO
BAN ASSAULT RIFLES WITH HIS VICE
PRESIDENT LEADING THE CHARGE.
>> PLUS, THIS HAPPENED
OVERNIGHT.
DICK'S SPORTING GOODS, BANNING
THE SALE OF AR-15 RIFLES AND
OTHER GUNS SIMILAR TO IT.
THE MODERN SPORTING RIFLE
SECTION OF ITS WEBSITE, TOTALLY
BLANK THIS MORNING.
THE COMPANY RELEASING A
STATEMENT THAT SAYS THIS.
OUT OF RESPECT FOR THE VICTIMS
AND THEIR FAMILIES, WE HAVE
REMOVED ALL GUNS IN OUR STORE
NEAREST TO NEWTOWN AND SUSPENDED
THE SALE OF MODERN SPORTING
RIFLES IN ALL OF OUR STORES
CHAIN WIDE.
>> GRIEF COUNSELORS WILL BE ON
HAND WHEN ALL OF THE CHILDREN IN
NEWTOWN HEAD BACK TO CLASS THE
FIRST TIME SINCE FRIDAY.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
WILL BE REMAIN CLOSED.
JESSICA REKOS WILL BE LAID TO
REST TODAY.
TAKE A LOOK ALTHOUGH HER BIG,
BEAUTIFUL EYES.
6-YEAR-OLD GIRL ADORED HORSES
AND COULDN'T WAIT UNTIL HER 10th
BIRTHDAY TO GET ONE.
HER FAMILY CALLED HER THE CEO OF
THE FAMILY.
IN CHARGE OF MAKING ALL OF THE
PLANS.
SHE ALSO LEAVES BEHIND TWO
YOUNGER BROTHERS.
JOHN.
>> WE'LL GO BACK TO NEWTOWN IN A
MOMENT TO SFLOR AIDA AND
SOLEDAD.
>>> FIRST, A DEVELOPING STORY IN
WASHINGTON.
SIGNIFICANT MOVEMENT IN THE
FISCAL CLIFF NEGOTIATIONS WITH
14 DAYS TO GO UNTIL HUGE ACROSS
THE BOARD TAX HIKES KICK IN AND
SPENDING CUTS.
THIS HAS NOT RECEIVED A GREAT
DEAL OF ATTENTION IN RECENT
DAYS, UNDERSTANDABLY SO.
OVERNIGHT, WE LEARNED PRESIDENT
OBAMA MADE AN EYE OPENING NEW
OFFER IN TALKS WITH HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER.
UNDER THE NEW PROPOSAL, TACK
RATES GO UP ONLY ON INCOMES
ABOVE 400,000.
FOR YEARS, YOU WILL REMEMBER THE
PRESIDENT CAMPAIGNED ON THAT
NUMBER STARTING AT 250,000.
HE IS ALSO PART OF THIS DEAL
OFFER SPENDING CUTS WORTH ABOUT
$200 BILLION.
NOW, HOUSE SPEAKER BOEHNER HAS
REFUSED TO CONSIDER RAISING TAX
RATES, HE HAS NOW PRO POSSESSED
RAISING TAXES ON HOUSEHOLDS
MAKING $1 MILLION.
CLEARLY BOTH SIDES ARE BUDGING
FROM THEIR INITIAL POSITIONS.
DAN LOTHIAN IN WASHINGTON WITH
THE LATEST.
GOOD MORNING, DAN.
>> IT WAS SPEAKER BOEHNER WHO
FIRST OPENED THE DOOR TO TAX
INCREASES OF THOSE UPPER INCOME
AMERICANS, THOSE OVER $1 MILLION
SO ONCE HE MADE THAT MOVEMENT,
WE SAW THIS DRAMATIC DEVELOPMENT
OVERNIGHT FROM PRESIDENT OBAMA,
WHO AS YOU POINTED OUT ON THE
CAMPAIGN TRAIL AND IN RECENT
DAYS, HAD SAID THAT IT WAS A
NONSTARTER.
TAXES HAD TO GO UP ON THOSE OVER
$250,000.
THOSE HOUSEHOLDS MAKING MORE
THAN $250,000.
HES HAS RAISED THAT TO $450,000.
MANY ARE ENCOURAGED BY THE
MOVEMENT.
IN ADDITION TO THAT, THE
PRESIDE
PRESIDENT PROPOSING 1.2 TRILLION
IN REVENUE, DOWN FROM 1.4
TRILLION AND 1.2 TRILLION IN
SPENDING CUTS.
HOUSE REPUBLICANS SAY THIS IS A
STEP IN THE RIGHT DIRECTION, BUT
THEY DON'T THINK THE PRESIDENT'S
MATH ADDS UP AND LEANS TOO
HEAVILY TOWARD TAX INCREASES.
WE EXPECT PUSHBACK FROM SENIORS
AND OTHERS WHO DEPEND ON
ESSENTIAL SECURITY.
AS PART OF THE PRESIDENT'S PLAN,
HE'S ALSO PROPOSING TO LOWER THE
COST OF LIVING INCREASES FOR
SOCIAL SECURITY BENEFICIARIES.
CERTAINLY THERE, WILL BE SOME
RESISTANCE TO THIS.
A BIG DEVELOPMENT HAPPENING ON
THIS FRONT.
>> DAN LOTHIAN IN WASHINGTON,
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
LET'S GO BACK TO SOLEDAD AND
ZORAIDA IN NEWTOWN.
>> THANKS, JOHN.
THE GUN CONTROL DEBATE IN THIS
COUNTRY HAS BEEN REIGNITED BY
THE MASSACRE IN THIS COUNTRY AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
MORE AMERICANS ARE SUPPORTING
THE IDEA OF TIGHTER GUN LAWS IN
THE AFTERMATH OF THE TRAGEDY.
LET'S GET TO EMILY SCHMIDT, LIVE
FROM WASHINGTON, D.C.
LET'S START WITH THE POLLS,
EMILY?
WHAT DO THEY SHOW US?
>> WE TAKE A LOOK AT THREE NEW
POLLS OUT.
THEY SHOW THERE HAS BEEN A
SIGNIFICANT, MAYBE TEMPORARY, WE
DON'T KNOW, REACTION TO WHAT
PEOPLE THINK ABOUT GUN CONTROL
AFTER THE NEWTOWN SHOOTINGS.
I WANT TO SHOW YOU FIRST OF ALL,
A CBS NEWS POLL, SAYING SHOULD
THERE BE MORE STRICT GUN CONTROL
LAWS?
UP 18% LAST WEEKEND OVER WHEN
THE QUESTION WAS ASKED IN APRIL.
DO YOU SUPPORT OR CONTROL
STRICTER GUN CONTROL LAWS?
LAST POLL TAKEN IN AUGUST,
SHOWED THE NUMBER GOING UP 5%.
PEW RESEARCH DID A SURVEY, DO
YOU THINK THE SHOOTINGS REFLECT
A BROADER SOCIETAL ISSUE?
WHEN THAT QUESTION WAS ASKED
AFTER THE AURORA, COLORADO,
SHOOTINGS, 24% SAID YES.
AFTER THE NEWTOWN SHOOTINGS, 47%
SAY THAT IS THE CASE.
THAT IS WHY WE ARE HEARING THIS
BROADER CONVERSATION NOW.
>> DAN MALLOY.
>> IN THE NEXT HALF HOUR, WE'LL
BE JOINED BY CONGRESSWOMAN
SHEILA JACKSON LEE, A TEXAS
DEMOCRAT CALLING FOR AN
IMMEDIATE BAN ON ALL ASSAULT
WEAPONS.
THANK YOU FOR THE UPDATE.
WE APPRECIATE THAT.
ZORAIDA.
>> NEWTOWN SCHOOLS WILL REOPEN
TODAY.
TWO HOURS LATER THAN USUAL.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY REMAINS AN
ACTIVE CRIME SCENE AND IS THE
ONLY SCHOOL THAT WILL REMAIN
CLOSED IN THE AREA.
BACK TO A PRODUCTIVE ROUTINE.
MENTAL HEALTH EXPERTS SAY THAT
IT'S A GOOD IDEA.
THE PAIN IS STILL GOING TO
LINGER.
SANDRA ENDOLIVE IN THE CENTER OF
NEWTOWN.
>> ZORAIDA, STUDENTS, PARENTS,
TEACHERS, MAY FEEL A BIT
ANXIOUS, BUT IT COULD BE THE
FIRST STEP TOWARD HEALING.
IN THE WAKE OF TRAGEDY, A STEP
TOWARD NORMALCY, FOR NEWTOWN
KIDS, THAT MEANS GOING BACK TO
SCHOOL.
>> WE ALSO ARE GOING TO BE A
LITTLE BIT WORRIED BECAUSE WE
KNOW WHAT WE THOUGHT WAS A
SECURE SCHOOL HAD THIS HAPPEN TO
THEM.
>> BUT FACING FEAR MAY BE THE
FIRST STEP TO OVERCOME THIS
TRAGEDY.
>> CHILDREN HAVE TO GET BACK TO
SCHOOL.
IF WE LET THIS SORT OF TERROR IN
OUR LIVES ANYWHERE IN THIS
COUNTRY WIN, WE'VE LOST.
WE HAVE TO GET OUR KIDS BACK TO
SCHOOL AGAIN.
>> CLASSES RESUMING FOR 5,400
STUDENTS IN THE DISTRICT, EXCEPT
FOR THOSE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
MONDAY, ALL SCHOOLS CLOSED AS
TEACHERS AND ADMINISTRATORS
TRAIN WITH EXPERTS ON HOW TO
HANDLE THE AFTERMATH.
MANY PARENTS WE SPOKE WITH,
AGREE KIDS BELONG BACK IN
SCHOOL.
>> I THINK THAT ONE OF THE BIG
THINGS WE HAVE TO DO IS HAVE
SOME SORT OF NORMALCY, AND
SCHOOL IS PART OF THAT.
>> UNFORTUNATELY, YOU KNOW,
WE'RE LIVING IN THIS WORLD WHERE
SOMETIMES EVIL PREVAILS
SOMETIMES, BUT WE'RE JUST
BELIEVING THAT GOOD WILL
OVERCOME THIS.
>> Reporter: SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY REMAINS A CRIME
SCENE.
FURNITURE AND SUPPLIES MOVED TO
CHALK HILL MIDDLE SCHOOL IN
NEIGHBORING MONROE, WHERE SANDY
HOOK STUDENTS WILL EVENTUALLY
RESUME CLASSES.
>> WHEN THE CHILDREN COME IN,
WHENEVER THE SCHOOL IS STARTED,
THEY WALK INTO A CLASSROOM, IT
WILL LOOK AS CLOSE AS POSSIBLE
TO THEIR CLASSROOM THAT THEY
LEFT.
>> Reporter: GRIEF COUNSELORS
AND POLICE WILL BE PRESENT AT
NEWTOWN SCHOOLS TODAY AND
THROUGH THE WEEKEND.
PRINCIPALS HAVE ASKED PARENTS TO
MAKE SURE THEY TALK TO KIDS
ABOUT THE TRAGEDY BEFORE THEY
HEAD BACK INTO THE CLASSROOMS,
BECAUSE YOU NEVER KNOW WHAT
FELLOW STUDENTS MAY SAY, AND, OF
COURSE, TEACHERS WILL ALSO TALK
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED IN AN
AGE-APPROPRIATE MANNER.
ZORAIDA, SOLEDAD.
>> ALL RIGHT, SANDRA ENDO,
REPORTING LIVE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>>> CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR DAN
MALLOY IS CALLING FOR A
NATIONWIDE MOMENT OF SILENCE
FRIDAY MORNING, EXACTLY ONE WEEK
AFTER THE SHOOTING AT THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND
CALLING ON CHURCHES TO RING
BELLS 26 TIMES, ONCE FOR EACH OF
THE VICTIMS KILLED IN FRIDAY'S
SCHOOL MASSACRE.
THE GOVERNOR CHOKING UP WHEN
EXPLAINING WHY HE TOOK IT UPON
HIMSELF FRIDAY MORNING TO TELL
WAITING FAMILIES THAT THEIR LUED
ONES WERE NOT COMING OUT.
>> IT WAS EVIDENT TO ME THAT
THERE WAS A RELUCTANCE TO TELL
PARENTS AND LOVED ONES THAT THE
PERSON THEY WERE WAITING FOR WAS
NOT GOING TO RETURN.
I MADE THE DECISION THAT TO HAVE
THAT GO ON ANY LONG ER WAS WRON.
>> MALLOY ALSO SAYS HE SUPPORTS
ACTION AT THE FEDERAL LEVEL TO
TIGHTEN THE NATION'S GUN CONTROL
LAWS.
YOU KNOW, THE LITTLE GIRL,
JESSICA REKOS WHO DIED, THEY
WERE AT THE FIREHOUSE WITH THE
GOVERNOR.
THEY WERE WAITING AND WAITING,
AND THEY GOT INTO THEIR LITTLE
GIRL'S BED AND WAITED UNTIL
POLICE CAME TO THE HOME.
>> AT 1:00 IN THE MORNING.
>> 1:00 IN THE MORNING.
TERRIBLE.
>>> IN THE NEXT HALF HOUR ON
"EARLY START," DAVID OWENS WILL
JOIN US WITH THE LATEST ON THE
POLICE INVESTIGATION OF THE
20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER WHO
SHATTERED SO MANY LIVES IN
NEWTOWN.
THAT'S AHEAD.
>>> COMING UP IN THE 7:00 HOUR,
WE'LL SPEAK WITH SENATOR JOE
MANCHIN.
A WEIGH DEMOCRAT.
NRA MEMBER, BUT SAYS NOW IS THE
TIME TO ACT TO TIGHTEN UP THE
GUN LAWS.
>>> AND THE TIDE COULD BE
TURNING ON GUN CONTROL IN THIS
COUNTRY.
AND A WALL STREET FIRM TAKING A
STAND.
WHAT THEY ARE DOING, STRAIGHT
AHEAD.
[ Tissue Box ]
HE SAID NASAL CONGESTION.
YEAH...I HEARD HIM.
[ Female Announcer ] TYLENOL®
COLD MULTI-SYMPTOM NIGHTTIME
RELIEVES NASAL CONGESTION.
NYQUIL® COLD AND FLU DOESN'T.
PLAYS A KEY ROLE
THROUGHOUT OUR LIVES.
One A Day Men's 50+
IS A COMPLETE MULTIVITAMIN
DESIGNED FOR MEN'S HEALTH
CONCERNS AS WE AGE.
IT HAS 7 ANTIOXIDANTS
TO SUPPORT CELL HEALTH.
One A Day Men's 50+.
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
♪
BECOMING
PART OF THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
TREES WILL TALK TO NETWORKS
WILL TALK TO SCIENTISTS
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE.
CARS WILL TALK TO ROAD SENSORS
WILL TALK TO STOPLIGHTS
ABOUT TRAFFIC EFFICIENCY.
THE AMBULANCE WILL TALK
TO PATIENT RECORDS
WILL TALK TO DOCTORS
ABOUT SAVING LIVES.
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
THE NEXT BIG THING?
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
♪
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
♪
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
MAKE A WISH!
I WISH WE COULD
LIE HERE FOREVER.
I WISH THIS TEST DRIVE WAS OVER,
SO WE COULD HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
TEST DRIVE!
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A JETTA.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN,
$0 DUE AT SIGNING, $0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
BECAUSE FOR EVERY TWO POUNDS
YOU LOSE
THROUGH DIET AND EXERCISE,
ALLI CAN HELP YOU
LOSE ONE MORE
BY BLOCKING
SOME OF THE FAT YOU EAT.
LET'S FIGHT FAT WITH ALLI.
♪
>>> ALL RIGHT.
WELCOME BACK TO "EARLY START."
I'M JOHN BERMAN.
CHRISTINE ROMANS, MINDSING YOUR
BUSINESS.
SOME INTERESTING BUSINESS NEWS.
>> THE COMPANY THAT MAKES THE
MILITARY STYLE RIFLE IS A
COMPANY CALLED FREEDOM GROUP AND
BASICALLY OWNED BY A BUNCH OF
INVESTORS, CERBERUS PRIVATE
EQUITY GROUP, AND TEACHER'S
PENSION FUND MONEY THAT INVESTS
IN CERBERUS, YOU SEE A
CALIFORNIA TEACHERS PENSION FUND
GIVING MONEY TO CERBERUS,
CREATING FREEDOM GROUP, WHICH
OWNS BUSHMASTER, THE COMPANY
THAT MAKES THE MILITARY STYLE
RIFLE USED IN THE KILLINGS.
TODAY, WE'RE HEARING FROM
CERBERUS, THEY ARE GOING TO SELL
FREEDOM GROUP, WHICH OWNS
BUSHMASTER, CERBERUS IS GOING TO
SELL IT.
THIS IS WHAT THEY SAY.
THEY SAY IN THE STATEMENT, IT IS
APPARENT THE SANDY HOOK TRAGEDY
IS A WATERSHED EVENT THAT HAS
RAISED THE NATIONAL DEBATE ON
GUN CONTROL TO AN UNPRECEDENTED
LEVEL IT IS NOT OUR ROLE TO TAKE
POSITIONS TO ATTEMPT TO SHAPE OR
INFLUENCE THE GUN CONTROL POLICY
DEBATE, HOWEVER, THERE ARE
ACTIONS THAT WE AS A FIRM CAN
TAKE.
THE CALIFORNIA TEACHERS PENSION
FUND ARE INVESTORS IN CERBERUS
AND THAT OPTIC, THAT CHAIN FROM
TEACHERS HERE TO A PRODUCT HERE
THAT IS USED TO KILL TEACHERS IS
A DIFFICULT OPTIC TO SETTLE.
ACCORDING TO FRIENDS AT
"FORTUNE."
THERE ARE A LOT OF PRODUCTS THAT
CAN BE USED RESPONSIBLY OR
IRRESPONSIBLY.
AND IN THIS CASE IT WAS USED
NO THAT A TRAGIC EVENT LIKE THIS
OCCURRED, I'M SURE IT IS
SOMETHING WE WILL BE DISCUSSING
GOING FORWARD, WHETHER
CALIFORNIA TEACHERS PENSIONS
FUND SHOULD BE USED TO FUND GUN
MANUFACTURERS.
THIS IS A PRIVATE COMPANY -- THE
BUSHMASTER COMPANY IS A PRIVATE
COMPANY.
BUT THERE ARE SOME PUBLIC
COMPANIES.
THE TWO BIG PUBLIC COMPANIES
DOWN EITHER 3% ON THE STOCK
EXCHANGE OR 5% ON THE STOCK
EXCHANGE.
A COMPANY CALLED OLIN, MAKES
AMMUNITI
AMMUNITION, UP JUST A LITTLE
BIT.
GUN SHOPS ARE SEEING A SPIKE IN
INTEREST IN BUYING WEAPONS,
BECAUSE GUN OWNERS ARE CONCERNED
ABOUT THE GUN CONTROL DEBATE
RIGHT NOW, BIG, BIG RETAILERS
WHERE YOU CAN BUY SOCCER GEAR
FOR YOUR KIDS AND BUY MILITARY
STYLE ASSAULT RIFLE.
DICK'S WILL STOP SELLING SOME
SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPONS AND
STOPPING ALL GUN SALES IN THE
STORE CLOSEST TO NEWTOWN.
I HAVE A CALL INTO FRIDAY.
ON FRIDAY EARLY AFTERNOON, I
GOOGLED BUSHMASTER 223.
FIRST THING THAT CAME UP WAS A
SPONSORED LINK TO WALMART.
SAYING I COULDN'T GET IT ONLINE
BUT GO TO CARNEY, NEW JERSEY.
SAYS IT AIMS STRAIGHT AND TRUE,
A MILITARY STYLE RIFLE.
YOU DON'T SEE THAT ON THE
WALMART WEBSITE.
NOT CLEAR IF THEY ARE NO LONGER
ADVERTISING THE GUN OR NO LONGER
WILL SELL IT.
>> I'M FASCINATING ABOUT WHAT
CERBERUS HAS DONE.
THEY ARE IN BUSINESS TO MAKE
MONEY AND CLEARLY MADE A TENSION
THAT OWNING THIS COMPANY THAT
MADE THE BUSHMASTER IS BAD
BUSINESS.
>> PEOPLE WHO FOLLOW PRIVATE
EQUITY THIS MORNING SAYING, WOW,
THIS IS A BIG MOVE.
THE COMPANY SAYING IN A PRESS
RELEASE, NOT TAKING A STAND.
PEOPLE WHO COVER PRIVATE EQUITY
SAY IT'S RARE.
USUALLY COMPANIES CAN WEATHER
ANY KIND OF POLITICAL FALLOUT.
BUT FREEDOM GROUP, WHICH
CERBERUS CREATED, OWNS NOT JUST
BUSHMASTER, BUT A SUITE OF TEN
DIFFERENT COMPANIES INVOLVED IN
FIREARMS AND AMMUNITION
INDUSTRY.
THE WHOLE GROUP UP FOR SALE.
>> WHAT IS THE ONE THING WE NEED
TO KNOW ABOUT MONEY?
>> STOCK FUTURES ARE UP.
AND WE'RE SEEING INCREMENTAL
EVIDENCE THAT THE FISCAL CLIFF
COULD RESOLVE.
THAT WOULD BODE WELL FOR
MARKETS.
STOCK FUTURES.
>> YOU GET THE SENSE THAT THE
MARKET WOULD LOVE IT, IF AND
WHEN THEY REACH A DEAL.
>> THEY HAVE TO DECIDE WHO
WASHINGTON DECIDED IS RICH.
IS IT $200 GRAND, $400 GRAND, $1
MILLION?
ONCE THEY COME UP WITH THAT,
THEY CAN DECIDE ON BUDGET CUTS.
>>> TRIBUTES POURING IN FOR A
GIANT OF THE U.S. SENATE.
DANIEL INOUYE, SERVED HAWAII
SINCE THE DAY IT BECAME A STATE
IN 1959.
NOW DIED AT THE AGE OF 88 FROM
RESPIRATORY PROBLEMS, INOUYE THE
SECOND LONGEST SERVING MEMBER
EVER, RIGHT AFTER ROBERT BYRD.
HE LOST AN ARM, CHARGING MACHINE
GUN LEST NESTS ITALY AND EARNED
THE MEDAL OF HONOR.
HE WITNESSED THE BOMBING OF
PEARL HARBOR AS A HIGH SCHOOL
STUDENT.
A TOWERING FIGURE, NOW GONE.
>>> TODAY, CONGRESS MAY RECEIVE
A REPORT BY AN INDEPENDENT PANEL
THAT EXAMINED THE DEADLY ATTACK
ON U.S. CONSULATE IN BENGHAZI.
THE REPORT WAS ORDERED BY
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON.
SHE WILL NOT TESTIFY DUE TO
ILLNESS.
THE STOMACH BUG, FELL OVER, GOT
A CONCUSSION.
THE ATTACK KILLED FOUR
AMERICANS, INCLUDING CHRIS
STEVENS, U.S. AMBASSADOR TO
LIBYA.
>>> JAMES CLAPPER STAYING ON.
HE AGREED TO REMAIN FOR THE
FORESEEABLE FUTURE.
CLAPPER TAKEN A LOT OF HEAT FOR
THE RESPONSE TO THE SEPTEMBER
11th ATTACKS ON THAT U.S.
MISSION IN BENGHAZI.
>>> FEDEX, GROUNDED.
HUNDREDS OF PACKAGES NEVER MADE
IT TO THEIR NEBRASKA
DESTINATIONS.
POSTAL INSPECTORS SAY A DELIVERY
DRIVER WORKING AS A PRIVATE
CONTRACTOR FOR FEDEX WAS SPOTTED
DUMPING THE PACKAGES FROM HIS
TRUCK ONTO THE STREET LOST LAST
MONTH.
ONLY 30 OF MORE THAN 400
PACKAGES WERE FOUND INTACT AND
FINALLY DELIVERED.
THE DRIVER, AS YOU CAN IMAGINE,
HE WAS FIRED.
>>> THE NEW YORK METS, EXPORTING
CY YOUNG AWARD WINNER, R.A.
DICKEY.
A 38-YEAR-OLD KNUCKLE BALLER.
SUCH A GREAT STORY.
WENT FROM THE SCRAP HEAP TO THE
KING OF THE HILL LAST YEAR,
WINNING THE CY YOUNG.
20-6 FOR THE METS.
ONE OF THE TRUE GOOD GUYS IN
BASEBALL.
>>> A MOTHER AND BLOGGER PUTTING
THE ISSUE OF MENTAL ILLNESS
FRONT AND CENTER, DECLARING I
ADAM AM LANZA'S MOTHER.
WE'LL HEAR FROM HER.
IT IS CONTROVERSIAL.
COMING UP.
PEOPLE HAVE DOUBTS
ABOUT TAKING ASPIRIN FOR PAIN.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
WITH ODOR FREE ASPERCREME.
POWERFUL MEDICINE
RELIEVES PAIN FAST,
WITH NO ODOR.
SO ALL YOU NOTICE IS RELIEF.
ASPERCREME.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
YOU'RE WATCHING "EARLY START,"
LIVE FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
IT IS AN EMOTIONAL AND DIFFICULT
DAY HERE.
AS SOME CHILDREN HEADING BACK TO
SCHOOL.
>> THE MOTHER OF NOAH POZNER, A
6-YEAR-OLD BOY KILLED IN THE
MASS SHOOTING, RELEASED THE
EULOGY SHE GAVE YESTERDAY BEFORE
SHE BURIED HER SON, CALLED HER
LITTLE MAN.
SOME WAS PUBLISHED IN "THE NEW
YORK TIMES."
IT BEGINS LIKE THIS.
"THE SKY IS CRYING AND THE FLAGS
ARE AT HALF MAST.
IT IS A SAD, SAD DAY.
BUT IT IS ALSO YOUR DAY, NOAH.
MY LITTLE MAN.
I WILL MISS YOUR FORCEFUL AND
PURPOSEFUL LITTLE STEPS STOMPING
THROUGH OUR HOUSE, I WILL MISS
YOUR PERPETUAL SMILE, THE
TWINKLE IN YOUR DARK BLUE EYES,
FRAMED BY EYELASHES THAT WOULD
BE THE ENVY OF ANY LADY IN THIS
ROOM.
SHE ENDS HEULOGY BY SAYING THIS.
I WILL JOIN YOU SOME DAY, BUT
NOT TODAY.
MAMA LOVES YOU LITTLE MAN IS HOW
SHE ENDS IT.
THE WHOLE THING IS REPRINTED IN
"THE NEW YORK TIMES."
>> WE WERE TALKING ABOUT THE
COURAGE IT TAKES TO GIVE THE
EULOGY FOR YOUR OWN CHILD.
>> I DON'T KNOW HOW YOU CAN DO
THAT.
>> THERE HE IS.
BEAUTIFUL SMILE ON HIS FACE.
THE WAY SHE WOULD WANT HIM
REMEMBERED.
>>> THE MOTHER OF A MENTALLY ILL
CHILD, UNDER FIRE FOR THE BLOG
POSTING WITH THE TITLE "I ADAM
AM LANZA'S MOTHER."
THE BLOG POST WAS A CRY FOR
HELP.
SHE WRITES ABOUT THE
DIFFICULTIES OF PARENTING A
TEENAGE SON WHO SHE DESCRIBES AS
SERIOUSLY DISTURBED.
LONG SPOKE TO ERIN BURNETT LAST
NIGHT.
>> SOMETIMES FOR NO APPARENT
REASON, HE WILL JUST TURN INTO
THIS ABSOLUTE RAGING -- I DON'T
KNOW HOW TO DESCRIBE IT.
WOULD YOU HAVE TO SEE IT TO
BELIEVE IT.
I STOPPED AND SAID TO MYSELF.
THIS ISN'T NORMAL.
I HAVE TO FACE UP TO THE FACT
THAT I HAVE A SICK SON, AND WE
NEED HELP.
>> LIZA TELLING CNN THAT SHE
LOVES HER SON, BUT HE "TERRIFIES
ME."
>> I HAVE TALKED TO MANY PARENTS
OF MENTALLY ILL CHILDREN AND
ADULTS THAT SAY THE SAME THING.
THEY ARE COMPLETELY AT A LOSS.
THE ONLY THING SOMETIMES THAT
CAN BE DONE IS BRING CRIMINAL
CHARGES TO GET THEM COMMITTED,
GET THEM CRIMINALLY
INCARCERATED.
HER SON IS 13 YEARS OLD.
>> AND THE OLDER THEY GET, THEY
BECOME STRONGER, SO THE FEAR
ABSOLUTELY MAKES SENSE.
>> THE POSTAL SERVICE IS
ESTABLISHING A POST OFFICE BOX
FOR ANYONE WHO WOULD LIKE TO
REACH OUT TO THE PEOPLE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THE ADDRESS IS MESSAGES OF
CONDOLENCE, P.O. BOX 3700,
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
AND THE ZIP CODE, 06470.
>> TO FIND OUT HOW YOU CAN HELP
THOSE AFFECTED BY THIS TRAGEDY,
GO TO CNN.COM/IMPACT.
I WENT TO THE SITE HERE, NOT
ONLY CAN YOU GET INFORMATION ON
HOW YOU CAN HELP THOSE AFFECTED,
BUT IF YOU NEED SOME HELP ALSO,
PERHAPS ON HOW TO TELL YOUR
CHILD ABOUT THIS TRAGEDY, HOW TO
EXPLAIN IT.
THERE ARE LIKS HERE AND LINKS TO
THE FACEBOOK PAGES SET UP FOR
THESE CHILDREN AS WELL.
A LOT OF INFORMATION FOR YOU IF
YOU WOULD LIKE.
>>> MEANTIME, PRESIDENT OBAMA,
HIS POINT MAN, AS HE GETS READY
TO PUT GUN CONTROL ON THE
AGENDA, MORE ON THAT, COMING UP.
list of almost two thousand
corporate partners -
companies like Microsoft,
American Red Cross and Adobe -
to create options for you.
Not only that, we're using what
we learn from these partners
to shape our curriculum, so that
when you find the job you want
you'll be a perfect fit.
Let's get to work.
to the number 1 club
in the world.
The potential of
Manchester United unlocked.
NYSE Euronext.
Unlocking the world's potential.
WHY THEY HAVE A
RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
TONIGHT OUR GUEST,
THOMAS SARGENT.
NOBEL LAUREATE
IN ECONOMICS,
AND ONE OF THE MOST CITED
ECONOMISTS IN THE WORLD.
PROFESSOR SARGENT,
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT CD RATES WILL
BE IN TWO YEARS?
NO.
IF HE CAN'T, NO ONE CAN.
THAT'S WHY ALLY HAS
A RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
ALLY BANK.
YOUR MONEY NEEDS AN ALLY.
PRETTY SWEET, HUH?
CUTE.
BUT DON'T YOU HAVE ANY APPS
ON YOUR PHONE
THAT CAN MAKE YOUR LIFE
EASIER?
WHO DO YOU THINK I AM,
Quicken Loans?
AT Quicken Loans, WE'LL PROVIDE
YOU WITH MYQL MOBILE.
THIS AMAZINGLY USEFUL APP
ALLOWS YOU
TO TAKE PICTURES
OF YOUR MORTGAGE DOCUMENTS
USING AN iPhone
OR Android SMART PHONE...
SO YOU CAN EASILY
SEND THEM TO US.
ONE MORE WAY Quicken Loans
IS Engineered to Amaze.
OOH, LA-LA!
>>> THE TIDE COULD BE TURNING ON
THE GUN CONTROL DEBATE.
A MAJOR CORPORATION AND EVEN
SOME REPUBLICANS SHOWING SIGNS
OF CHANGE.
>>> AN ANXIOUS MORNING IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
MANY STUDENTS AND PARENTS HERE,
KIND OF PUT THEIR FEAR ASIDE AS
THEY HEAD BACK TO SCHOOL.
>> TWO-WEEK WARNING UNTIL THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
ONE-ON-ONE MEETING AT THE WHITE
HOUSE RESULTS IN MAJOR MOVEMENT
TOWARD A DEAL.
WELCOME BACK TO "EARLY START."
GLAD YOU ARE WITH US.
I'M ZORAIDA SAMBOLIN.
>> AND I'M SOLEDAD O'BRIEN.
WE BEGIN TAKING A LOOK AT THE
LATEST IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
DEVELOPMENTS REALLY IN THE
NATION'S GUN CONTROL DEBATE
FIRST AND FOREMOST.
FOUR DAYS AFTER THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL MASSACRE,
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS TAKING
ACTION.
THE "WASHINGTON POST" ORDERED
HIS CABINET PUT TOGETHER
PROPOSALS, THAT COULD INCLUDE
REINSTATING A BAN ON ASSAULT
RIFLES.
VICE PRESIDENT JOE BIDEN, ASKED
TO LEAD THE CHARGE ON THIS.
>>> ALSO, DICK'S SPORTING GOODS
HAS REMOVED ALL GUNS FROM ITS
STORE CLOSE TOAST NEWTOWN AND
SUSPENDING SALES OF MODERN
SPORTING RIFLES CHAIN WIDE.
>>> AND GRIEF COUNSELORS WILL BE
ON HAND AS CHILDREN HEAD BACK TO
SCHOOL.
THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
REMAINS CLOSED.
JESSICA REKOS WILL BE LAID TO
REST TODAY.
SHE ADORED HORSES AND COULDN'T
WAIT UNTIL HER 10th BIRTHDAY
WHEN HER PARENTS PROMISED TO BUY
HER A HORSE.
SHE IS THE OLDEST CHILD IN HER
FAMILY.
SHE LEAVES BEHIND TWO YOUNGER
BROTHERS, AND, OF COURSE, HER
MOM AND DAD.
AND I HAVE TO TELL YOU, THEY
CALLED HER THE CEO OF THE
FAMILY, BECAUSE SHE WAS IN
CHARGE OF EVERYTHING.
THE ONE ALWAYS MAKING PLANS.
>> RAN THE WHOLE THING.
>> AND SHE ALWAYS LEFT LITTLE
NOTES AROUND THE HOUSE AND HER
MOTHER ACTUALLY DISCOVERED ONE
ONCE SHE HAD BEEN KILLED AND SHE
SAID IT BROUGHT HER COMFORT.
IT SAID I LOVE YOU, MOMMY.
REMEMBER, JESSICA REKOS THIS
MORNING.
JUST 6 YEARS OLD.
>>> GAMERFITNATION.COM IS
CALLING FOR A SHOW OF SUPPORT
FOR THE VICTIMS OF THE NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, MASSACRE.
IT'S ASKING FOR GAMERS TO JOIN
IN A DAY OF CEASE-FIRE, FRIDAY,
DECEMBER 21st.
>>> TITANS STAR RUNNING BACK
CHRIS JOHNSON, PAYING TRIBUTE TO
ALL 26 VICTIMS ON HIS CLEATS
DURING MONDAY NIGHT FOOTBALL.
BROKE OFF A 94-YARD TOUCHDOWN
RUN IN THOSE CLEATS.
14-10 WIN OVER THE JETS.
>> PROPELLED BY THOSE NAMES.
>>> ANOTHER BIG STORY TODAY.
NEW DEVELOPMENTS IN THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
BACK TO JOHN BERMAN IN NEW YORK.
GOOD MORNING, JOHN.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
THERE MAY BE A RAY OF HOPE IN
THE FISCAL CLIFF DISCUSSIONS.
OVERNIGHT, WE LEARNED PRESIDENT
OBAMA GAVE SOME PRETTY SERIOUS
GROUND IN HIS PROPOSAL TO JOHN
BOEHNER.
IN HIS REVISED PITCH, THE
PRESIDENT SUGGESTING THAT TAX
RATES WOULD RISE ON INCOMES OVER
$400,000.
PREVIOUSLY, HE WANTED HIGHER
TAXES ON HOUSEHOLDS STARTING AT
$250,000 AND OFFERING NEW
SUBPOENAI I
SPENDING CUTS.
THE PRESIDENT IS NOW PAND SPEAK
BOEHNER, WILL MEET WITH
COLLEAGUES TO UPDATE THEM ON
NEGOTIATIONS.
IT COULD BE A DIFFICULT MEETING.
DAN LATHI ILOTHIAN IN WASHINGTO
APPEARS WITHIN THE LAST 24
HOURS, SOME REAL, CONCRETE
MOVEMENT.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
THE BIG QUESTION, CAN SPEAKER
BOEHNER SELL THIS PROPOSAL TO
HOUSE REPUBLICANS?
IT WAS A BIG BREAK THROUGH
YESTERDAY WHEN SPEAKER BOEHNER
MET WITH PRESIDENT OBAMA AT THE
WHITE HOUSE FOR 45 MINUTES AND
THIS IS DRAMATIC, BECAUSE THE
PRESIDENT HAD HELD NOW FOR SO
LONG THAT TAXES HAD TO GO UP ON
HOUSEHOLDS MAKING MORE THAN
250,000 AND NOW THE PRESIDENT
RAISING THAT CEILING TO 400,000.
IN ADDITION, THE PRESIDENT
LOOKING FOR 1$1.2 TRILLION IN NW
REVENUE.
DOWN FROM 1.4 TRILLION AND 1.2
TRILLION IN SPENDING CUTS.
THIS MEETS THE DEMAND THAT
SPEAKER BOEHNER HAD FOR EQUAL
SPENDING CUTS TO NEW REVENUE.
HOUSE AIDES SAY THE MATH DOESN'T
ADD UP.
THEY SEE THIS AS A MOVE IN THE
RIGHT DIRECTION, THEY SAY IT'S
NOT BALANCED.
SPEAKER BOEHNER, SPOKESMAN
BRENDAN BUCK SAYING A PROPOSAL
THAT INCLUDES 1.3 TRILLION IN
REVENUE FOR $930 BILLION IN
SPENDING CUTS CANNOT BE
CONSIDERED BALANCED.
STILL SOME DIFFERENCES REMAIN.
BUT MANY VIEW THIS AS A STEP IN
THE RIGHT DIRECTION, JOHN.
>> WHAT YOU ARE SEEING IS
REPUBLICAN CRITICISM TO THE
PRESIDENT'S PROPOSAL.
HE WILL TAKE HEAT FROM THE LEFT
HERE ON WHAT HE'S WILLING TO
COMPROMISE ON.
HE HAS GIVEN GROUND ON A KEY
INDEXING, A MEASUREMENT OF
INSPLAGS.
TANTO MOUNT TO CUTTING GROWTH IN
THE ENTITLEMENTS.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
AND YOU CAN EXPECT A VERY STRONG
PUSHBACK FROM THOSE IN HIS
PARTY, UNION MEMBERS AS WELL.
ALSO WHEN YOU LOOK AT WHAT THE
PRESIDENT IS PROPOSING FOR
SOCIAL SECURITY, WHERE HE IS
TALKING ABOUT LOWERING THE COST
OF -- LOWERING THE COST OF
LIVING INCREASES FOR SOCIAL
SECURITY BENEFICIARIES, THIS IS
SOMETHING THAT NO DOUBT A SENIOR
ADVOCATES WILL PUSH BACK ON.
WE DO SEE QUITE A BIT OF
PROGRESS HAPPENED HERE OVER THE
LAST FEW HOURS, THERE IS STILL A
LITTLE BIT MORE WORK TO DO
BEFORE AN AGREEMENT CAN BE
REACHED.
>> A BIG MEETING BETWEEN SPEAKER
BOEHNER AND HOUSE REPUBLICANS,
10:00 A.M., COULD BE HUGELY
INTERESTING.
DAN LOTHIAN, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
>>> HUNDREDS OF HOLIDAY GIFTS
MIGHT NOT GET THERE ON TIME.
COMING UP, WAIT UNTIL YOU HEAR
ABOUT WHAT ONE DELIVERY DRIVER
DID WITH A WHOLE LOT OF
PACKAGES.
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>>> WAY TOO FAST.
>> AND AS WE JUST MENTIONED, THE
PRESIDENT HAS ASKED VOICE
PRESIDENT BIDEN TO TAKE THE LEAD
IN EXAMINING THE COUNTRY'S GUN
LAWS, OUTSPOKEN GUN CONTROL
ADVOCATE, NEW YORK CITY MAYOR
MIKE BLOOMBERG HAD THIS TO SAY
YESTERDAY.
>> GUN VIOLENCE IS A NATIONAL
EPIDEMIC, AND A NATIONAL
TRAGEDY.
THAT DEMANDS MORE THAN WORDS.
WE ARE THE ONLY INDUSTRIALIZED
COUNTRY THAT HAS THIS PROBLEM.
IN THE WHOLE WORLD, THE ONLY
ONE.
AND THAT'S WHY WE NEED IMMEDIATE
NATIONAL ACTION FROM THE
PRESIDENT AND FROM CONGRESS.
IT SHOULD BE AT THE TOP OF THEIR
AGENDA.
>> OUR NEXT GUEST SAYS SHE'S
TAKING IMMEDIATE ACTION,
CONGRESSWOMAN SHEILA JACKSON
LEE, A DEMOCRAT FROM THE STATE
OF TEXAS, CURRENTLY WORKING ON A
NEW BILL THAT SHE SAYS COULD
PREVENT MORE HORRIFIC MASS
MURDERS.
NICE TO HAVE YOU WITH US,
CONGRESSWOMAN.
APPRECIATE YOUR TIME.
THE PRESIDENT AS I MENTIONED
WHEN WE STARTED THIS SEGMENT,
HAS ASKED THE VICE PRESIDENT TO
SORT OF LEAD WHAT HIS CABINET
WILL BE COMING UP WITH, SOME
IDEAS, AND HOPEFULLY GOOD
PROPOSALS ON HOW TO END THE
VIOLENCE.
YOU SAID THERE SHOULD BE AN
IMMEDIATE BAN ON ALL ASSAULT
WEAPONS.
GIVE ME -- WHAT WOULD BE COVERED
UNDER WHAT YOU HAVE IN MIND?
>> WELL, FIRST OF ALL, LET ME,
AGAIN, OFFER MY DEEPEST SYMPATHY
TO THE FAMILIES OF THOSE
BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN AND THE
FAMILIES OF THOSE WONDERFUL
TEACHERS.
SOLEDAD, THE WHOLE NATION MOURNS
AND THIS IS A SIGNIFICANT MOMENT
IN HISTORY.
BAR NONE, THAT SURPASSES ANY OF
THE HORRIFIC TRAGEDIES WE FACE,
AND THE CALL IS TO ACTION.
I HOPE TO COLLABORATE WITH
MEMBERS OF CONGRESS, CERTAINLY
SENATOR FEINSTEIN, VERY
THOUGHTFUL IN LEGISLATION WITH
AN ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN AND THERE
SHOULD BE A NATIONAL DISCUSSION
THAT TALKS ABOUT A NUMBER OF
OTHER ITEMS AS WELL.
CLOSING THE GUN SHOW LOOPHOLE IS
REALLY CLOSING THE GENERAL
LOOPHOLE.
60% OF AMERICA'S GUNS ARE BOUGHT
WITHOUT A BACKGROUND CHECK, AND
THERE ARE INSTANCES WHERE WE
MIGHT HAVE PROTECTED INNOCENT
VICTIMS IF WE WOULD HAVE KNOWN
WHAT THE CONDITION OF THE
PURCHASER WAS.
WE NEED IN NATIONAL DIALOG.
I'M DELIGHTED THAT THE PRESIDENT
HAS TASKED VICE PRESIDENT BIDEN
WITH THE EFFORT.
CERTAINLY HE IS ONE WHO CAN
BRING MEMBERS OF CONGRESS FROM
BOTH SIDES OF THE AISLE, BUT
MORE IMPORTANTLY, BOTH HOUSES
TOGETHER.
WE HAVE TO STOP THE DIVIDE
BETWEEN YOU WANT TO TAKE MY
GUNS, OR YOU'RE IN AN URBAN AREA
AND I'M IN A RURAL AREA, I'M
FAMILIAR WITH GUNS, WE'VE GROWN
UP WITH GUNS.
THIS IS A NATIONAL DIALOG, NOT
ABOUT THE SECOND AMENDMENT, WE
RESPECT THE SECOND AMENDMENT.
IT'S IN THE BILL OF RIGHTS, BUT
IT'S A DIALOG ABOUT SAVING LIVES
AND THAT'S WHAT THIS GUN
REGULATION LEGISLATION WOULD BE,
NOT GUN CONTROL.
>> LET'S RUN THROUGH SOME OF THE
OTHER THINGS THAT YOU ARE
CALLING FOR IN WHAT YOU ARE
PROPOSING, IN ADDITION TO
CLOSING THE GUN SHOW LOOPHOLE,
ARE YOU CALLING FOR A MORE
STRUCTURED MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEM
FOR FAMILIES THAT WOULD ALLOW
THEM TO GET IMMEDIATE ASSISTANCE
IN REGARD TO MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES, LOOKING AT PRIMARY AND
SECOND SCHOOLS WHERE THEY MAY
NEED TO HAVE REINFORCED BULLET
PROOF WINDS AND REINFORCED
SECURE ENTRANCES, EXPANDING LATE
LAWS HOLDING ADULTS RESPONSIBLE
FOR SECURING THEIR WEAPONS.
YOU HAVE PROPOSED THE GUN SAFETY
ACT EVERY YEAR FOR THE PAST TEN
YEARS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK THERE WILL BE
A GROUNDSWELL OF SUPPORT FOR
WHAT YOU ARE PROPOSING NOW THAT
GOES FAR -- MUCH FARTHER THAN
THE PROPOSAL YOU'VE HAD EVERY
YEAR FOR TEN YEARS?
>> YOU KNOW, I THINK THAT THE
COMMON SENSE DISCUSSION AND NEED
TO ACT IN A COMMON SENSE MANNER
HAS NOW RISEN TO THE HIGHEST
LEVEL OF THE CONSCIOUSNESS OF
AMERICANS.
AND FOR THOSE OF US WHO HAD A
PASSION TO PROTECT OUR CHILDREN,
BUT TO PROTECT OTHERS, NOW SEE A
WAY FORWARD, IF WE JUST LOOKED
AT THE NUMBERS AND SAW THE
PERCENTAGES OF INCIDENCES OF
HOMICIDE AND SUICIDE, THEY ARE
HIGHER WHERE GUNS ARE AVAILABLE.
WE HAVE ALL HEARD THE STORY OF
THE CHINESE INDIVIDUAL WHO
STABBED 22 CHILDREN.
BUT THEY ALL LIVED.
WE WISH THAT HADN'T HAPPENED.
I TRULY BELIEVE IF ADULTS ARE
RESPONSIBLE ABOUT SECURING THEIR
GUNS, ABOUT PUTTING A SAFETY --
HAVING SAFETY LOCKS, PROTECTING
OUR CHILDREN, WE WOULD BE BETTER
OFF.
I ALSO BELIEVE VERY, VERY, VERY
SINCERELY THAT IF WE ALLOW
PEOPLE TO BE UNSTIGMATIZED, IF
YOU WILL, WITH RESPECT TO MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES IN THEIR FAMILY,
THEY WOULD MORE EAGERLY OR
AGGRESSIVELY SEEK HELP AS I
BELIEVE THIS PERPETRATOR NEEDED.
HE NEEDED ADDITIONAL HELP, AND
HE CERTAINLY DIDN'T NEED TO BE
TRAGICALLY AROUND GUNS.
AND ALSO I KNOW THAT OUR SCHOOLS
IN AMERICA ARE AGING.
I UNDERSTAND THAT.
BUT IF THOSE WHO ARE IN
LEADERSHIP ROLES WOULD LOOK AT
REINFORCED GLASS AND SECURE
ENTRY WAYS, THOSE ARE
POSSIBILITIES IN A VERY
DIFFICULT WORLD AND VERY
DIFFICULT CLIMATE.
PARENTS ARE LOOKING FOR ANSWERS,
AND WE MUST COMMIT TO THEM WHEN
THEIR CHILDREN LEAVE THEIR
PRECIOUS HOMES THAT THEY CAN GO
TO A PLACE OF SAFETY AND
SECURITY.
I THINK WE CAN LOOK WAY
COMMON-SENSE APPROACH, AND WHAT
I'VE OFFERED IS A COMMON-SENSE
APPROACH.
I LOOK FORWARD TO WORKING WITH
SENATOR FEINSTEIN AND MY OTHER
COLLEAGUES IN MOVING FORWARD AND
I THINK WE'VE RAISED AMERICA'S
CONSCIENCE ON HOW PRECIOUS THESE
LIVES ARE.
>> CONGRESSWOMAN, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH FOR YOUR TIME.
WE APPRECIATE IT.
>> THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
>> RIGHT BACK TO JOHN BERMAN.
JOHN IS IN NEW YORK.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH, SOLEDAD.
SOUTH CAROLINA CONGRESSWOMAN TIM
SCOTT WILL REPLACE RETIRED
SENATOR JIM DEMINT.
SHE CHOSE SCOTT FOR HIS
BACKGROUND AND VISION IN
BUSINESS AND HIS COMMITMENT TO
CONSERVATIVE PRINCIPLES.
SCOTT WILL BE THE ONLY
AFRICAN-AMERICAN IN THE SENATE.
JIM DEMINT IS LEADING TO HEAD UP
A CONSERVATIVE THINKTANK.
>> HUNDREDS OF PACKAGES,
ABSOLUTELY, POSITIVELY, DIDN'T
MAKE IT TO THEIR HOLIDAY
DESTINATION.
WHY?
A DRIVER DECIDED TO DUMP MORE
THAN 400 DELIVERY ITEMS ONTO A
STREET IN NEBRASKA.
ONLY ABOUT 30 SURVIVED INTACT
AND WERE FINALLY DELIVERED.
THE INCIDENT OCCURRED LAST
MONTH, AND, YES, THE DRIVER HAS
BEEN FIRED.
>>> TRAVELING AT A SPEED OF
ALMOST 4,000 MILES PER HOUR.
TWO NASA PROBES HAVE CRASHED
INTO THE MOON.
THE GOOD NEWS, THIS WAS PLANNED
AND DONE ON PURPOSE AT THE END
OF THEIR MISSION.
NASA HAS NAMED THE SPOT WHERE
THE TWO PROBES CRASHED IN HONOR
OF THE LATE ASTRONAUT SALLY
RIDE, THE FIRST WOMAN IN SPACE,
AND MEMBER OF THE GRAIL MISSION
TEAM THAT FIRST PUT THE PROBES
IN SPACE.
NEWTOWN'S PARENTS GET READY TO
SEND MOST OF THEIR KIDS BACK TO
SCHOOL, DETECTIVES ARE FOCUSING
ON WHAT THEY FOUND IN THE
SHOOTER'S HOME.
LIVE BACK TO NEWTOWN, COMING UP.
HAVE A GOOD NIGHT.
HERE YOU GO. YOU, TOO.
I'M GOING TO DREAM
ABOUT THAT STEAK.
ABOUT THAT TIRAMISU.
WHAT A NIGHT, HUH?
BUT, UM, CAN THE TEST DRIVE
BE OVER NOW?
HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A PASSAT.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN, $0 DUE AT SIGNING,
$0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
>>> WELCOME BACK.
YOU'RE WATCHING "EARLY START."
WE'RE LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, THIS MORNING.
PEOPLE ARE COMING TOGETHER,
PRESSING ON AS THEY GRIEVE THE
LOSS OF THE VICTIMS AT THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE FORMER CHAIRWOMAN OF
NEWTOWN'S BOARD OF EDUCATION,
DESCRIBING HOW SHE FEELS JUST
HOLLOW WITH WOLF BLITZER.
>> OH, IT'S BEEN HORRIFIC, FROM
THE MOMENT WE ALL HEARD THE
NEWS, IT WAS DEVASTATING TO KNOW
THAT SOMEONE HAD COME INTO THE
SCHOOL WITH A GUN.
THAT ALONE WAS HORRIBLE ENOUGH,
BECAUSE IT'S A PLACE OF PEACE
AND JOY, BUT NOW AS WE GO
FORWARD AND WE'VE LEARNED THE
NAMES AND GOING THROUGH THE
GRUELING PROCESS OF THE
FUNERALS, IT'S VERY, VERY, VERY
HARD.
EVERYONE USES THE WORD HOLLOW,
THAT'S WHERE WE'RE AT RIGHT NOW.
>> THIS MORNING, A BIG STEP IN
THE RECOVERY PROCESS FOR NEWTOWN
FAMILIES AND THEIR STUDENTS.
GOING BACK TO SCHOOL.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL US
LOGISTICALLY ABOUT HOW IT'S
SUPPOSED TO GO TODAY, SANDRA?
>> Reporter: ROUGHLY 5,400
NEWTOWN STUDENTS WILL RETURN TO
SCHOOL TODAY, SOLEDAD.
THERE WILL BE A TWO-HOUR DELAY,
AND STUDENTS, PARENTS, TEACHERS,
MAY BE ANXIOUS RETURNING BACK TO
SCHOOL.
BUT CLEARLY A LOT OF EXPERTS AND
OFFICIALS SAY THIS IS THE FIRST
STEP TOWARD NORMALCY, PART OF
THE HEALING PROCESS.
AS YOU MENTIONED, SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY STUDENTS WILL STILL
REMAIN OUT OF SCHOOL RIGHT NOW.
THEY ARE TRYING TO FIND MORE
ACCOMMODATIONS.
FOR THE 5,400 STUDENTS, THERE
WILL BE GRIEF COUNSELORS AND
POLICE BACK AT SCHOOL WHEN
CLASSES RESUME, AS WELL AS
TEACHERS DISCUSSING WHAT
HAPPENED IN AN AGE-APPROPRIATE
MANNER.
PRINCIPALS HAVE ASKED PARENTS TO
TALK TO THEIR KIDS BEFORE THEY
RETURN TO SCHOOL ABOUT THE
INCIDENT.
YOU NEVER KNOW WHAT OTHER
STUDENTS MAY SAY ABOUT THE
MASSACRE AND WHAT MAY HAPPEN IN
TERMS OF THE CLASSROOM SETTING.
BUT CLEARLY THEY ARE READY TO
TAKE ON A LOT OF QUESTIONS THAT
STUDENTS MAY HAVE AND A LOT OF
FEELINGS, THE EMOTION, THE PAIN
THAT THIS COMMUNITY IS FEELING.
SOLEDAD.
>> SANDRA ENDO, THANK YOU,
SANDRA.
ZORAIDA.
>>> THIS MORNING, THE
INVESTIGATION ONGOING AS TO WHAT
COULD HAVE CAUSED THE TRAGEDY AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY TO OCCUR.
AUTHORITIES ARE DIGGING DEEPER
INTO THE GUN AND COMPUTER USAGE
OF THE GUNMAN.
THE GUNMAN IN THE NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, SHOOTING, KILLED
HIMSELF BEFORE ANYONE COULD GET
THE REASONS THAT COMPELLED HIM
TO KILL MORE THAN 2 DOZEN
PEOPLE.
DAVID OWENS, A CRIME REPORTER
FOR "THE HARTFORD COURANT" FOR
THE PAST 24 YEARS.
HE IS JOINING US NOW.
THANK YOU, WE APPRECIATE IT.
WE KNOW THEY SEIZED A SMASHED
COMPUTER, HARD DRIVE SMASHED.
"THE NEW YORK TIMES" REPORTS
THEY GOT NOTHING FROM IT, BUT
THE STATE POLICE SAY THEY ARE
HAPPY WITH THE PROGRESS THEY ARE
MAKING.
WHERE DO YOU THINK THEY STAND?
>> THE STATE POLICE HAVE BEEN
GATHERING ALL KINDS OF
INFORMATION AND EVIDENCE FROM
THE HOME, FROM THE SCHOOL.
THEY DON'T COMMENT DIRECTLY ON
WHAT THEY SEIZE.
BUT LIEUTENANT VANCE AT THE
STATE POLICE SAID THEY HAVE
OBTAINED HELPFUL EVIDENCE,
IMPORTANT EVIDENCE, THAT THEY
BELIEVE WILL HELP LEAD THEM TO
AN ANSWER AS TO WHY THIS
HAPPENED.
>> NOW, THEY ARE SUGGESTING IT
WILL BE A WHILE BEFORE WE HEAR
ANYTHING CONCRETE.
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA OF HOW LONG
BEFORE PERHAPS WE'LL HAVE SOME
ANSWERS HERE?
>> I THINK IT COULD BE MONTHS.
CERTAINLY WEEKS.
WE HAD AN AWFUL SHOOTING SEVERAL
YEARS AGO HERE IN CONNECTICUT
AND THAT INVESTIGATION TOOK A
YEAR.
THE STATE POLICE ARE NOT IN A
RUSH TO GET THIS DONE.
THEY WILL TAKE AS LONG AS IT
TAKES.
>> YOU KNOW THIS COMMUNITY WELL.
HAVE YOU BEEN COVERING STORIES
HERE FOR 18 YEARS.
WHAT ARE YOUR IMPRESSIONS OF HOW
THIS AFFECTED THE IMMEDIATE
AREA?
>> EVERYWHERE IN CONNECTICUT, I
HAVE GONE, IN THE PAST FEW DAYS,
EVERYONE IS IMPACTED BY THIS.
EVERYONE TALKING ABOUT IT.
PEOPLE ARE JUST HORRIBLY BROKEN
UP, NOT TO THE DEGREE THAT THE
FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS AND THE
PEOPLE CLOSE TO THOSE PEOPLE IN
NEWTOWN ARE, BUT THE WHOLE STATE
IS MOURNING.
AND THE MORE I TALKED TO PEOPLE
ABOUT IT, THE MORE I FIND THAT
PEOPLE ARE LINKED SOMEHOW TO
THIS TRAGEDY.
THEY HAVE A FRIEND, A COWORKER.
WHEN PEOPLE RETURN TO WORK
MONDAY, THEY LEARNED THAT IN
MANY INSTANCES THAT FRIENDS HAD
SUFFERED A LOSS IN THIS TRAGEDY.
>> AND, DAVID, TELL US YOUR
PERSONAL STORY ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED WHEN YOU WERE GOING OUT
TO COVER THIS STORY.
WHAT DID ANOTHER REPORTER ASK
YOU TO DO?
>> ONE OF MY COLLEAGUES, BILL
LUKEHART, I HAVE WORKED WITH HIM
AT THE "HARTFORD COURANT" FOR
YEARS, AND WE WERE IN NEWTOWN
FRIDAY MORNING AND WE MET BY THE
FIREHOUSE AT THE FOOT OF THE
SCHOOL.
AND HE TOLD ME HIS STEPDAUGHTER
WAS SUBSTITUTING AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY AND HE WROTE HER NAME
DOWN, LAUREN ROUSSEAU ON A PIECE
OF PAPER FROM A NOTEBOOK AND
HANDED IT TO ME, AND ASKED ME TO
BE ON THE LOOKOUT FOR HER AND OF
COURSE, WE FOUND OUT LATER THAT
SHE WAS ONE OF THE TEACHERS WHO
DIED.
>> DID YOU HAVE TO TELL HIM
THAT?
>> NO.
THE EDITORS IN HARTFORD HAD
BEGUN TO HAVE AN IDEA THAT THERE
WAS A PROBLEM.
BILL LEARNED QUICKLY TOO,
BECAUSE THE STATE POLICE HAD
BEGUN ASSIGNING TROOPERS TO THE
FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS TO HELP
THEM BEGIN TO HAVE A LIAISON
WITH STATE AUTHORITIES AND BILL
HEADED HOME TO BE WITH HIS
FAMILY.
>> WOW.
DAVID, I KNOW THIS IS PERSONAL
FOR ENTHUSIASM IS YOUR FAMILY AS
WELL.
WE APPRECIATE YOUR TIME,
REPORTING FOR "THE HARTFORD
COURANT."
THANK YOU.
BACK TO JOHN BERMAN IN NEW YORK.
>>> NEW YORK METS EXPORTING CY
YOUNG AWARD WINNER R.A. DICKEY.
DICKEY TRADED TO THE TORONTO
BLUE JAYS IN A SEVEN-PLAYER DEAL
AND SENDING ONE OF BASEBALL'S
TOP CATCHING PROCKS BACK TO NEW
YORK.
DICKEY, A GREAT STORY, WENT FROM
BASEBALL'S SCRAP HEAP TO THE
KING OF THE HILL LAST YEAR,
WINNING THE CY YOUNG, GOING 20-6
FOR THE NEW YORK METS.
>>> HOW ABOUT THIS AS THE
SUBJECT OF MARTIN SCORSESE'S
NEXT FILM.
BILL CLINTON.
HE WILL DIRECT A DOCUMENTARY ON
CLINTON FOR HBO CLINTON IS SAID
TO BE COOPERATING FULLY WITH THE
SCORSESE PROJECT.
>>> STORMY WEATHER IN THE WEST
AND MIDWEST COULD AFFECT TRAVEL
PLANS TODAY.
WANT TO GET TO CKAREN McGINNIS.
NASTY WEATHER UP HERE TOO.
>> YEAH, BOTH EAST AND WEST, WE
HAVE SOME STORM SYSTEMS THAT
WILL MAKE DIFFICULT TRAVEL AS WE
GO TOWARD THE BIG TRAVEL
WEEKEND.
TAKE A LOOK AT VIDEO OUT OF DES
MOINES, WASHINGTON THIS IS JUST
SOUTH OF SEATTLE.
THEY SAW CRASHING WAVES, HIGH
WINDS, THE STORM SYSTEM IS AIMED
AT THE WEST COAST.
WE'LL SEE SNOW LEVELS IN SEATTLE
DOWN TO AROUND 400 FEET.
TRAVELING TO THE MIDWEST, LOOK
OUT.
ARE YOU EXPECTING 3 TO 6 INCHES
OF SNOWFALL IN THE NEXT SEVERAL
DAYS, JOHN.
>> THANK YOU, KAREN MAGNIFICEC .
WHILE GOING SHOELESS
AND METAL-FREE IN SECONDS.
AND YOU...RENT FROM National.
BECAUSE ONLY National
LETS YOU CHOOSE ANY CAR
IN THE AISLE...AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE A FULL-SIZE
OR ABOVE,
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
NOW THIS...WILL WORK.
[ Male Announcer ]
JUST LIKE YOU, BUSINESS PRO.
JUST LIKE YOU.
GO National.
GO LIKE A PRO.
JUST LIKE YOU.
WITH TWO TIMES THE POINTS
ON DINING IN RESTAURANTS,?
YOU MAY FIND
YOURSELF ASKING
WHY NOT, A LOT.
CHASE SAPPHIRE PREFERRED.
THERE'S MORE TO ENJOY.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME FOR CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
OUR SPECIAL EDITION OF