plans,
including Medicare.
Find your co-pay at
MyFlexPen.com.
♪
MANY HOT DOGS
ARE WITHIN YOU.
TRY PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO,
IT'S THE POWER OF PEPTO,
BUT IT FITS IN YOUR POCKET.
NOW TELL THE WORLD
DANIEL...
OF PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN DIARRHEA HITS,
KAOPECTATE STOPS IT FAST.
POWERFUL LIQUID RELIEF
SPEEDS TO THE SOURCE.
FAST.
[ Male Announcer ]
STOP THE UH-OH FAST
WITH KAOPECTATE.
>>> HEY, THERE.
WELCOME BACK TO CNN'S CONTINUING
COVERAGE OF THE TRAGEDY AT SANDY
HOOK, ELEMENTARY.
WE ARE HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
HEADING TOWARDS THE BOTTOM OF
THE HOUR.
I'M KATE BOLDUAN AND JOHN BERMAN
WILL BE BACK TO JOIN ME IN A
COUPLE OF MINUTES.
LET'S CATCH YOU UP ON WHAT WE
KNOW THIS SUNDAY.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL HEAD TO
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WHERE HE
WILL MEET WITH THE FAMILIES OF
THE VICTIMS.
THE PRESIDENT WILL ALSO SPEAK AT
A VIGIL, AN INTERFAITH VIGIL
TONIGHT.
MANY PEOPLE LOOKING FORWARD TO
HEARING HIS WORDS.
WE ALSO KNOW 12 OF THE VICTIMS
WERE BOYS AND 8 WERE GIRLS.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER RELEASED
THE NAMES OF ALL OF THE VICTIMS
YESTERDAY.
ALL OF THE CHILDREN WERE EITHER
6 OR 7 YEARS OLD.
WHILE 6 OF THEM HAVE  THE VICTI
ADULTS, ALL WERE WOMEN WORKING
AT THE SCHOOL.
UNITED WAY SET UP A FUND TO
COLLECT DONATIONS FOR VICTIMS'
FAMILIES AND THE COMMUNITY AS A
WHOLE.
IT'S CALLED THE SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL SUPPORT FUND.
ALL DONATIONS WILL GO DIRECTLY
TO THOSE AFFECTED.
MANY WAYS TO IMPACT YOUR WORLD
TODAY.
>>> WE STILL DON'T KNOW MUCH,
THOUGH, ABOUT THE SHOOTER, ADAM
LANZA.
SO MANY QUESTIONS AND VERY FEW
ANSWERS.
WHAT TYPE OF PERSON HE WAS.
I WANT TO BRING IN CNN CHIEF
MEDICAL CORRESPONDENT DR. SANJAY
GUPTA.
HEARING A LOT OF THE SAME THINGS
WE ARE.
ONE THING A SOURCE HAS TOLD CNN
THAT A RELATIVE SAYS THAT ADAM
LANZA HAD A FORM OF AUTISM.
AUTOMATICALLY PEOPLE JUMPED TO
TRY TO MAKE CONNECTIONS, BUT YOU
HAVE TO BE VERY, VERY CAREFUL TO
TRY TO CONNECT THIS HORRIBLE
VIOLENCE TO ANYTHING HAVING TO
DO WITH AUTISM.
>> I THINK SO.
AND I THINK, KATE, YOU CAN
PROBABLY EVEN TAKE IT A STEP
FURTHER.
THERE REALLY IS JUST NO EVIDENCE
OF A LINK BETWEEN AUTISM OR
ASBERINGER'S OR ANYTHING ON THE
AUTISM SPECTRUM TO PLANNED
VIOLENCE.
THIS IDEA THAT PEOPLE HAVE
VIOLENT OUTBURSTS OR REACTIVE
VIOLENCE, THERE'S BEEN SOME
NOTION OF THAT.
BUT YESTERDAY I DECIDED TO LOOK
INTO THIS A LITTLE BIT MORE.
ONE OF THE LARGEST STUDIES OF
132 PEOPLE AND ONE THAT EVERYONE
QUOTES.
IN THAT STUDY ONLY THREE PEOPLE
HAD EVIDENCE OF ANY VIOLENCE
WHATSOEVER AND REACTIVE
VIOLENCE.
I THINK WE CAN DISPEL THIS MYTH
THAT SOMEHOW AUTISM CONTRIBUTED
TO THIS PLANNED VIOLENCE THAT
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT HERE.
>> ALSO, WE HAVE SO MANY
QUESTIONS ABOUT THE SHOOTER AND
THE FAMILIES ARE JUST SEEKING
FOR SOME ANSWERS.
THIS WHOLE COMMUNITY ARE SEEKING
FOR ANSWERS AND REALLY JUST
STILL REELING FROM THIS TRAGEDY.
THERE HAVE BEEN MANY SUPPORT
GROUPS THAT HAVE SET UP, BUT
ALSO A CRISIS CENTER THAT WAS
SET UP YESTERDAY AND YOU WERE
TELLING ME THAT YOU VISITED THAT
CRISIS CENTER.
WHAT DID YOU SEE, WHAT DID YOU
HEAR?
>> I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO EXPECT,
KATE, IT IS SO RAW AND WHETHER
OR NOT PEOPLE WOULD JUST WANT TO
BE AT HOME WITH THEIR FAMILIES
OR ACTUALLY GO TO A PLACE LIKE
THIS.
THEY WANTED TO GO.
I CAN TELL YOU THAT.
PROBABLY AT LEAST 100 CARS IN
THE PARKING LOT.
IT WAS A DIFFERENT ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, OBVIOUSLY, REID
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WHERE THEY SET
THIS UP.
PSYCHIATRISTS, PSYCHOLOGISTS AND
CHILDREN'S COUNSELORS ALL THERE
AND WHAT WAS STRIKING FAMILIES
GOING IN THERE AND STAYING FOR
SOME TIME, AS WELL.
NOT SOMETHING WHERE THEY WERE
GOING FOR A SHORT PERIOD OF TIME
AND YOU REALLY GOT THE IDEA FROM
TALKING TO PEOPLE THAT THE
COMMUNITY AS A WHOLE WAS ALMOST
AN INDIVIDUAL, MEANING THAT
INSTEAD OF BEING ISOLATED AND
SORT OF HAVING TO DEAL WITH THAT
AND THE WORSENING FEELINGS THAT
MIGHT BRING.
SOMEONE IS GOING THROUGH THE
SAME THING YOU WERE GOING
THROUGH WAS PART OF THE CRISIS
CENTER SET UP IN TIME AND PHONE
LINES THAT PEOPLE COULD SIMPLY
PICK UP THE PHONE AND CALL.
IT'S HARD TO KNOW WHAT THE
IMPACT WILL BE, BUT, CLEARLY,
PEOPLE WANTED TO USE THESE
SERVICES.
>> WHAT I'VE BEEN HEARING SINCE
I'VE BEEN ON THE GROUND AND
TALKING TO MANY RESIDENTS, SO
MANY PARENTS, NO MATTER WHAT
THEIR CHILDREN ARE.
THEY'RE STRUGGLING TO FIGURE OUT
HOW TO TELL THEIR CHILDREN ABOUT
WHAT'S TRANSPIRED.
IF -- HOW MUCH DETAIL TO GIVE
THEM AND REALLY EVERYONE IS
DEALING WITH THIS ON AN OWN
INDIVIDUAL LEVEL AND PARENTS
NEED TO BE STRONG FOR THEIR
KIDS.
>> PROBABLY A LOT OF YOUR
VIEWERS ALL OVER THE COUNTRY ARE
HAVING THOSE DISCUSSIONS.
I DON'T LIVE HERE, BUT MY KIDS
WERE ASKING ME THE SAME THINGS.
I HAVE A 7, 5 AND 3-YEAR-OLD.
I WILL TELL YOU THAT YOU WANT TO
BE HONEST WITH SOMETHING LIKE
THIS.
AND I THINK THIS WHOLE -- MY
DAUGHTER WANTED TO KNOW THE
NAMES OF PEOPLE YESTERDAY.
SHE WANTED TO KNOW THE NAMES OF
SOME OF THESE CHILDREN AND SHE
WANTED TO KNOW IF HER SCHOOL WAS
GOING TO BE A SAFE PLACE TO GO.
AND I SAID THIS NEVER HAPPENED
IN DADDY'S SCHOOL OR MOMMY'S
SCHOOL AND THIS HAPPENED NOW BUT
WE DO ALL WE CAN TO KEEP YOU
SAFE.
EVERYONE KNOWS THEIR KIDS BEST
AND THE GRAPHIC DETAILS, I
THINK, OBVIOUSLY, AGE
APPROPRIATE SORT OF THINGS.
BUT I THINK THAT'S PROBABLY LESS
NECESSARY THAN JUST LETTING THEM
TALK AND THEN FILLING IN SOME OF
THE GAPS FOR THEM.
I THINK IT'S ALSO IMPORTANT TO
REMEMBER THAT IN MEDICINE WE SAY
YOU CHECK YOUR OWN PULSE FIRST
BEFORE GOING INTO A SITUATION.
CHECK YOUR OWN FEELINGS FIRST.
DOESN'T MEAN YOU DON'T SHARE
YOUR FEELINGS, BUT YOU ALSO
DON'T WANT TO OVERWHELM THEM AND
OVERTALK THE KIDS WITH YOUR OWN
FEELINGS.
YOU ARE THERE TO SUPPORT THEM
EVEN THOUGH SOMETIMES IT SEEMS
LIKE THEY'RE SUPPORTING YOU, AS
WELL.
>> YOU'RE A NEURO SURGEON SO YOU
KNOW MORE ABOUT THE BRAIN AND
THE MIND THAN SO MANY.
DO YOU THINK AS PEOPLE ARE
TRYING TO FIND A MOTIVE, A
REASON WHY THIS MAN WENT INTO
THIS SCHOOL AND DID THIS
HORRIFIC, EVIL ACT, DO YOU THINK
IT WILL COME DOWN TO SOME KIND
OF MENTAL DISORDER, PERSONALITY
DISORDER?
>> I THINK THERE'S A VERY GOOD
CHANCE SOME SORT OF MENTAL
ILLNESS THAT MAYBE, AGAIN, NOT
ASPERG
ASPERGER'S OR AUTISM BUT
SOMETHING ELSE CONFOUNDING THIS.
HAVING COVERED A LOT OF THESE
STORIES TRAGICALLY OVER THE
YEARS AND YOU KNOW THIS, KATE,
SOMETIMES THE ANSWER IS
UNKNOWABLE.
SOMETIMES WE SIMPLY DON'T KNOW.
WE WERE TALKING ABOUT THIS
YESTERDAY.
THERE WILL BE AUTOPSIES AND
LOOKING AT TO TRY TO ANSWER
THESE QUESTIONS THAT YOU'RE
ASKING AND I DOUBT THEY'RE GOING
TO FIND SOMETHING WHERE THEY
SAY, THAT'S THE ANSWER.
>> NOTHING IS GOING TO BRING ANY
COMFORT TO THOSE FAMILIES.
>> I THINK YOU'RE RIGHT.
>> DR. SANJAY GUPTA, THANK YOU
SO MUCH.
GREAT TO SEE YOU.
>>> SANJAY A DOCTOR AND FATHER
HIMSELF OF THREE YOUNG GIRLS.
WE'LL BE BACK IN A FEW MINUTES
ON HOW NOT TO TALK TO YOUR KIDS
ABOUT THE TRAGEDY AND SOME TIPS
ON HOW YOU SHOULD TALK TO YOUR
KIDS ABOUT THIS TRAGEDY.
SANJAY, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>>> DO JUST WANT TO CORRECT AN
EARLIER REPORT RIGHT HERE ON CNN
THAT WE REPORTED ON EARLIER, THE
YOUNG VICTIMS WERE, IN FACT, 12
GIRLS AND 8 BOYS.
WE APOLOGIZE FOR THAT MISTAKE.
MANY MOVING PARTS HERE AS WE
COVER THIS STORY.
>>> WE WANT TO TELL YOU, THERE
ARE SO MANY INCREDIBLE STORIES
TO TELL YOU ABOUT.
ONE OF THE YOUNGEST VICTIMS,
WE'LL TELL YOU ABOUT ONE OF THE
YOUNGEST VICTIMS IN A MOMENT,
BUT, FIRST, HERE ARE THE NAMES
AND AGES OF ALL 26 PEOPLE KILLED
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
PEOPLE HAVE DOUBTS
ABOUT TAKING ASPIRIN FOR PAIN.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
THIS IS ANOTHER!
TA-DAA!
TRY CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG.
IT CLEANS SO WELL AND YOU CAN
USE UP TO FOUR TIMES LESS
THAN THE LEADING VALUE
BRAND.
OH! THERE IT IS.
THANKS SON.
HEY!
[ Female Announcer ]
CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG
HAS A DURACLEAN TEXTURE
THAT CAN HELP YOU GET CLEAN
WHILE STILL USING LESS.
AND IT'S FOUR TIMES STRONGER
VERSUS THE LEADING VALUE BRAND.
CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG HELPS KEEP
YOU AND YOUR UNDERWEAR CLEAN.
WE ALL GO. WHY NOT ENJOY THE GO
WITH CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG?
>>> LAST NIGHT FRIENDS AND
MOURNERS GATHERED IN STRATFORD,
CONNECTICUT, TO REMEMBER SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOLTEACHER
VICTORIA SOTO.
♪
YOU KNOW, YOU CAN SEE SEVERAL
PEOPLE IN THE CROWD WERE WEARING
GREEN.
THAT WAS VICTORIA'S FAVORITE
COLOR.
THE FIRST GRADE TEACHER WAS
KILLED ON FRIDAY MORNING.
SHE DIED TRYING TO PROTECT HER
STUDENTS.
VICTORIA SOTO WAS JUST 27 YEARS
OLD.
>>> EMILIE PARKER WAS JUST 6
YEARS OLD.
ANOTHER ONE OF THE VICTIMS OF
THIS TRAGEDY.
HER FATHER SPOKE PUBLICLY AND
VERY EMOTIONALLY LAST NIGHT.
HE'S ONE OF THE ONLY PARENTS TO
COME FORWARD TO TALK OPENLY
ABOUT THEIR TERRIBLE LOSS.
IT'S BECAUSE HE SAID HE WANTS
EVERYONE TO KNOW HOW SPECIAL HIS
LITTLE GIRL WAS.
>> I WOULD REALLY LIKE TO OFFER
OUR DEEPEST CONDOLENCES TO ALL
THE FAMILIES DIRECTLY AFFECTED
BY THIS SHOOTING.
IT'S A HORRIFIC TRAGEDY AND WE
WANT EVERYBODY TO KNOW THAT OUR
HEARTS AND OUR PRAYERS GO OUT TO
THEM.
THIS INCLUDES THE FAMILY OF THE
SHOOTER.
I CAN'T IMAGINE HOW HARD THIS
EXPERIENCE MUST BE FOR YOU.
AND I WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT OUR
FAMILY AND OUR LOVE AND SUPPORT
GOES OUT TO YOU, AS WELL.
MY DAUGHTER, EMILIE, WOULD BE
ONE OF THE FIRST ONES TO BE
STANDING AND GIVING HER LOVE AND
SUPPORT TO ALL THOSE VICTIMS.
BECAUSE THAT'S THE TYPE OF
PERSON THAT SHE IS.
NOT BECAUSE OF ANY PARENTING
THAT MY WIFE AND I COULD HAVE
DONE, BUT BECAUSE THOSE ARE THE
GIFTS THAT WERE GIVEN TO HER BY
HER HEAVENLY FATHER.
I HAVE TWO REALLY GOOD FRIENDS
AT HOME WHO SET UP A FACEBOOK
PAGE TO HELP RAISE MONEY FOR
EMILIE AND WHEN I'VE GOTTEN ON
THAT AND JUST SEEN THE NUMBER OF
PEOPLE WHO HAVE COMMENTED AND
EXPRESSED THEIR CONDOLENCES IT'S
BEEN QUITE OVERWHELMING.
AS THE DEEP PAIN BEGINS TO
SETTLES INTO OUR HEARTS, WE FIND
COMFORT REFLECTING ON THE
INCREDIBLE PERSON THAT EMILIE
WAS AND HOW MANY LIVES SHE WAS
ABLE TO TOUCH IN HER SHORT TIME
ON EARTH.
EMILIE WAS BRIGHT, CREATIVE AND
VERY LOVING.
EMILIE WAS ALWAYS WILLING TO TRY
NEW THINGS, OTHER THAN FOOD.
SHE LOVED TO USE HER TALENTS TO
TOUCH THE LIVES OF EVERYONE SHE
CAME INTO CONTACT WITH.
SHE WAS AN EXCEPTIONAL ARTIST
AND ALWAYS CARRIED AROUND HER
MARKERS AND PENCILS SO SHE NEVER
MISSED AN OPPORTUNITY TO DRAW A
PICTURE OR MAKE A CARD FOR THOSE
AROUND HER.
I CAN'T COUNT THE NUMBER OF
TIMES EMILIE NOTICED SOMEONE
FEELING SAD OR FRUSTRATED AND
WOULD RUSH TO FIND A PIECE OF
PAPER TO DRAW THEM A PICTURE OR
TO WRITE THEM AN ENCOURAGING
NOTE.
EMILIE'S CARDMAKING WAS
EXPRESSED BEAUTIFULLY THIS LAST
OCTOBER WHEN SHE PLACED A VERY
SPECIAL CARD THAT SHE HAD MADE
INTO THE CASKET WITH HER
GRANDPA, WHO ALSO JUST RECENTLY
DIED OF A TRAGIC ACCIDENT.
EMILIE WAS A MENTOR TO HER TWO
LITTLE SISTERS AND DELIGHTED IN
TEACHING THEM TO READ, DANCE AND
FIND THE SIMPLE JOYS IN LIFE.
EMILIE'S LAUGHTER WAS INFECTIOUS
AND ALL THOSE WHO HAD THE
PLEASURE TO MEET HER WOULD AGREE
THAT THIS WORLD IS A BETTER
PLACE BECAUSE SHE HAD BEEN IN
IT.
SHE WAS THEIR BEST FRIEND.
THEY WERE ALL BORN WITHIN THREE
YEARS OF EACH OTHER, SO, BY LAW,
THEY'RE VERY CLOSE.
SHE WAS TEACHING MY MIDDLE
DAUGHTER TO READ.
SHE WOULD HELP MY YOUNGEST
DAUGHTER LEARN HOW TO MAKE
THINGS, SHOW HER HOW TO DO
CRAFTS.
THEY LOOKED UP TO HER.
AND THEY LOOKED TO HER WHEN THEY
NEEDED COMFORT.
USUALLY THAT'S, THAT'S SAVED FOR
A MOM AND DAD.
BUT IT WAS REALLY SWEET TO SEE
THE TIMES WHEN ONE OF THEM WOULD
FALL OR GET THEIR FEELINGS HURT
HOW THEY WOULD RUN TO EMILIE TO
GET SUPPORT AND HUGS AND KISSES.
SHE WAS THE TYPE OF PERSON THAT
WOULD JUST LIGHT UP A ROOM.
SHE ALWAYS HAD SOMETHING KIND TO
SAY ABOUT ANYBODY.
HER LOVE AND THE STRENGTH THAT
SHE GAVE US AND THE EXAMPLE THAT
SHE SHOWED TO US IS REMARKABLE.
SHE IS AN INCREDIBLE PERSON.
AND I'M SO BLESSED TO BE HER
DAD.
>> EMIL IRXEY AIE AND HER FAMIL
JUST MOVED TO NEWTOWN EARLIER
THIS YEAR AND SHE WILL BE LAID
TO REST BACK IN UTAH.
QUESTIONS?
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
CAN YOUR MOISTURIZER DO THAT?
[ Female Announcer ]
DERMATOLOGIST RECOMMENDED
Aveeno HAS AN OAT FORMULA,
NOW PROVEN
TO BUILD A MOISTURE RESERVE,
SO SKIN CAN REPLENISH ITSELF.
THAT'S HEALTHY SKIN FOR LIFE.
ONLY FROM Aveeno.
WE DON'T LET FREQUENT HEARTBURN
COME BETWEEN US
AND WHAT WE LOVE.
SO IF YOU'RE ONE OF THEM PEOPLE
WHO GETS HEARTBURN
AND THEN TREATS DAY AFTER DAY...
BLOCK THE ACID WITH PRILOSEC OTC
AND DON'T GET HEARTBURN
IN THE FIRST PLACE!
[ Male Announcer ]
ONE PILL EACH MORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBURN.
THEY DID THAT OUT OF RESPECT FOR
THE VICTIMS.
TOM CRUISE WAS SUPPOSED TO BE IN
PITTSBURGH LAST NIGHT FOR THE
PREVIEW OF HIS NEW MOVIE, THE
PREMIERE "JACK REACHER."
THAT MOVIE BEGINS WITH THE SCENE
INVOLVING A SNIPER ATTACK.
>>> THE NEW YORK GIANTS, THE NEW
YORK JETS AND THE NEW ENGLAND
PATRIOTS ALL PLAN TO WEAR
PATCHES OR DECALS TO HONOR THE
VICTIMS WHEN THEY TAKE THE FIELD
TODAY.
IT IS SO HARD TO MAKE SENSE OUT
OF A TRAGEDY LIKE THIS, THE ONE
AT THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
SO HARD FOR ANYONE TO WRAP THEIR
HEADS AROUND IT, YET ALONE
CHILDREN, WHICH IS WHY I WANT TO
BRING IN OUR CHIEF MEDICAL
CORRESPONDENT DR. SANJAY GUPTA.
AN EMOTIONAL STORY FOR ALL OF US
AND PARENTS AROUND THE COUNTRY,
INCLUDING ME, I'M A PARENT TO 5
YEAR OLDS AND YOU'RE A PARENT.
WHAT DO WE TELL OUR KIDS BEFORE
THEY GO TO SCHOOL TOMORROW?
>> THE ONE THING I THINK IS
IMPORTANT AND YOUR KIDS DON'T
REALLY KNOW YET WHAT HAS
HAPPENED BUT SO MANY KIDS STILL
FIND OUT, JOHN.
IT'S IMPORTANT TO REALIZE THAT
EVEN WITH THE TV OFF, TALKING TO
OTHER PEOPLE, AS YOU SAY, IT'S A
STORY THAT HAS REALLY EVERYONE
IN THE COUNTRY HAS TALKED ABOUT.
YOU HAVE TO ASSUME THAT YOUR
KIDS ARE GOING TO KNOW
SOMETHING.
I THINK AT THAT POINT TO BE
TRANSPARENT.
I HAVE A 7, 5 AND 3-YEAR-OLD.
MY 7-YEAR-OLD ASKED ME THE NAMES
OF THE CHILDREN.
THEY WANT TO HUMANIZE THIS
IMMEDIATELY.
THAT'S JUST THEIR INSTINCT, I
THINK.
THEN TO FILL IN DETAILS AS IS
APPROPRIATE FOR THE AGE.
I MEAN, OBVIOUSLY, NOT BEING TOO
GRAPHIC, BUT ALSO NOT, IN ANY
WAY, NOT BEING TRUTHFUL.
SO, SHE ASK EED ABOUT HER OWN
SCHOOL AND IF IT WAS SAFE.
I REMINDED HER THIS NEVER
HAPPENED TO DADDY'S SCHOOL,
MOMMY'S SCHOOL AND NEVER
HAPPENED HERE.
I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT TO SAY
WE'LL KEEP YOU SAFE AND THIS IS
A BAD MAN THAT DID THESE THIS SI
THINK.
IT MAKES A DIFFERENCE, AND IT'S
GOING TO BE A MATURING
EXPERIENCE AS HARD AS IT IS TO
SAY FOR ALL KIDS.
I THINK THIS IS PART OF IT.
>> DO YOU WAIT FOR THEM TO COME
TO YOU?
I ASK IT SELFISHLY.
SHOULD I WAIT OR GO TO THEM AND
SAY LISTEN, SOMETHING BAD HAS
HAPPENED?
>> THE ADVICE SEEMS TO BE LET
THEM DICTATE THE CONVERSATION.
EVEN WHEN THEY DICTATE THE
CONVERSATION, EVEN TO ASK WHAT
DO YOU KNOW?
WHAT HAVE YOU HEARD?
ASK FIRST TO GET AN IDEA WHERE
THEY ARE, AND THEN START TO
ANSWER SOME QUESTIONS.
YOU DON'T WANT TO OVERTALK THEM.
I MENTIONED THIS EARLIER, BUT IN
MEDICINE WE SAY CHECK YOU'RE OWN
PULSE FIRST BEFORE GOING INTO A
SITUATION.
CHECKING YOUR OWN FEELINGS A
LITTLE BIT AS WELL.
THE GOAL I IMAGINED FOR YOU AND
ME IS TO BE A SOURCE OF SUPPORT
FOR THEM.
IN ORDER TO DO THAT YOU HAVE TO
MAKE SURE YOU HAVE YOUR OWN
FEELINGS IN CHECK.
IT'S HARD.
I SPENT A LOT OF LAST NIGHT JUST
WHEN I SHOULD HAVE BEEN SLEEPING
THINKING ABOUT THIS AS WELL.
>> YOU WANT TO BE A SOURCE OF
SUPPORT FOR THEM.
THE TRUTH IS THEY'VE BEEN A
SOURCE OF SUPPORT FOR ME THIS
WEEKEND.
SEEING THEM HAS MEANT SO MUCH TO
ME COVERING THIS.
WHAT ARE THE SIGNS YOU LOOK FOR
IN CHILDREN, BESIDES THE
QUESTIONS, ONCE THEY DO FIND
OUT, THE NEXT IT FEW DAYS, WHAT
TO LOOK FOR TO MAKE SURE THEY'RE
HANDLING THIS WELL?
>> VERY IMPORTANT.
WE THINK OF PTSD AS SOMETHING
ADULTS EXPERIENCE, BUT YOUNG
CHILDREN CAN.
EVEN THREE TO FOUR MONTHS OLD
ABOUT THREE-QUARTERS OF CHILDREN
HAVE SOME FORM OF PTSD MORE
EXPOSE TO THE VIOLENCE SAW
SOMETHING ARE THE MOST
TRAUMATIZED WITH THIS SORT OF
THING.
IT'S NOT FLASHBACKS TYPICALLY
EYRE HYPERVIGILANCE, BUT OFTEN
UP CHANGES IN PLAY.
REGRESS AND HAVE TEMPER
TANTRUMS, SLEEP, VERY IMPORTANT,
JOHN.
OVER THE NEXT FEW DAYS IF YOUR
CHILD IS SLEEPING WELL, THEY'RE
LIKELY TO COPE WELL IN THE LONG
RUN.
>> DR. SANJAY GUPTA, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
IT'S BE VERY HELPFUL TO ME AND
EVERYTHING OUT THERE.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S SIMPLE PHYSICS...
A BODY AT REST
TENDS TO STAY AT REST...
WHILE A BODY IN MOTION
TENDS TO STAY IN MOTION.
STAYING ACTIVE CAN ACTUALLY
EASE ARTHRITIS SYMPTOMS.
BUT IF YOU HAVE ARTHRITIS,
STAYING ACTIVE
CAN BE DIFFICULT.
PRESCRIPTION CELEBREX
CAN HELP RELIEVE ARTHRITIS PAIN
SO YOUR BODY
CAN STAY IN MOTION.
BECAUSE JUST ONE
200MG CELEBREX A DAY
CAN PROVIDE 24 HOUR RELIEF
FOR MANY WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND INFLAMMATION.
PLUS, IN CLINICAL STUDIES,
CELEBREX IS PROVEN TO IMPROVE
DAILY PHYSICAL FUNCTION
SO MOVING IS EASIER.
CELEBREX CAN BE TAKEN WITH
OR WITHOUT FOOD.
AND IT'S NOT A NARCOTIC.
YOU AND YOUR DOCTOR
SHOULD BALANCE THE BENEFITS
WITH THE RISKS.
ALL PRESCRIPTION NSAIDS,
LIKE CELEBREX, IBUPROFEN,
NAPROXEN, AND MELOXICAM
HAVE THE SAME
CARDIOVASCULAR WARNING.
THEY ALL MAY INCREASE
THE CHANCE
OF HEART ATTACK OR STROKE,
WHICH CAN LEAD TO DEATH.
THIS CHANCE INCREASES
IF YOU HAVE HEART DISEASE
OR RISK FACTORS
SUCH AS HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE
OR WHEN NSAIDS ARE TAKEN
FOR LONG PERIODS.
NSAIDS, INCLUDING CELEBREX,
INCREASE THE CHANCE OF SERIOUS
SKIN OR ALLERGIC REACTIONS
OR STOMACH AND INTESTINE
PROBLEMS,
SUCH AS BLEEDING AND ULCERS,
WHICH CAN OCCUR WITHOUT WARNING
AND MAY CAUSE DEATH.
PATIENTS ALSO TAKING ASPIRIN
AND THE ELDERLY
ARE AT INCREASED RISK FOR
STOMACH BLEEDING AND ULCERS.
DO NOT TAKE CELEBREX IF YOU'VE
HAD AN ASTHMA ATTACK, HIVES,
OR OTHER ALLERGIES TO ASPIRIN,
NSAIDS OR SULFONAMIDES.
GET HELP RIGHT AWAY IF YOU HAVE
SWELLING OF THE FACE OR THROAT,
OR TROUBLE BREATHING.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
YOUR MEDICAL HISTORY
AND FIND AN ARTHRITIS TREATMENT
FOR YOU.
VISIT CELEBREX.COM AND ASK
YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT CELEBREX.
FOR A BODY IN MOTION.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
♪
MANY HOT DOGS
ARE WITHIN YOU.
TRY PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO,
IT'S THE POWER OF PEPTO,
BUT IT FITS IN YOUR POCKET.
NOW TELL THE WORLD
DANIEL...
OF PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO.
>>> I'M VICTOR BLACKWELL AT THE
CNN HEADQUARTERS IN ATLANTA.
HERE'S AT LOOK AT OTHER STORIES
THIS MORNING.
>>> FT PHILIPPINES THE TOLL FROM
A DEVASTATING TYPHOON CONTINUES
TO CLIMB.
AUTHORITIES SAY MORE THAN 1,000
PEOPLE HAVE DIED AND IT'S FEARED
THE NUMBER WILL GO HIGHER SINCE
MORE THAN 800 PEOPLE ARE STILL
MISSING.
MANY ARE FISHERMEN AT SEA WHEN
THE STORM STRUCK.
THE