TO KNOW THAT YOU'RE NOT ALONE IN
YOUR GRIEF.
THAT OUR WORLD, TOO, HAS BEEN
TORN APART.
THAT ALL ACROSS THIS LAND OF
OURS, WE HAVE WEPT WITH YOU.
WE'VE PULLED OUR CHILDREN TIGHT,
AND YOU MUST KNOW THAT WHATEVER
MEASURE OF COMFORT WE CAN
PROVIDE, WE WILL PROVIDE.
WHATEVER PORTION OF SADNESS THAT
WE CAN SHARE WITH YOU TO EASE
THIS HEAVY LOAD, WE WILL GLADLY
BEAR IT.
NEWTOWN, YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
AS THESE DIFFICULT DAYS HAVE
UNFOLDED, YOU'VE ALSO INSPIRED
US.
WITH STORIES OF STRENGTH AND
RESOLVE AND SACRIFICE.
WE KNOW THAT WHEN DANGER ARRIVED
IN THE HALLS OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY, THE SCHOOL'S STAFF
DID NOT FLINCH.
THEY DID NOT HESITATE.
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG AND MARY
SHERLACH, VICKI SOTO, LAUREN
RUSSEAU, RACHEL DAVINO AND ANNE
MARIE MURPHY, THEY ALL RESPONDED
IN HOW WE HOPE WE ALL WOULD
RESPOND IN SUCH TERRIFYING
CIRCUMSTANCES, WITH COURAGE AND
WITH LOVE, GIVING THEIR LIVES TO
PROTECT THE CHILDREN IN THEIR
CARE.
WE KNOW THAT THERE WERE OTHER
TEACHERS WHO BARRICADED
THEMSELVES INSIDE CLASSROOMS AND
KEPT STEADY THROUGH IT ALL AND
REASSURED THEIR STUDENTS BY
SAYING WAIT FOR THE GOOD GUYS,
THEY ARE COMING.
SHOW ME YOUR SMILE.
AND WE KNOW THAT GOOD GUYS CAME,
THE FIRST RESPONDERS WHO RACED
TO THE SCENE HELPING TO GUIDE
THOSE IN HARM'S WAY TO SAFETY
AND COMFORT THOSE IN NEED,
HOLDING AT BAY THEIR OWN SHOCK
AND THEIR OWN TRAUMA, BECAUSE
THEY HAD A JOB TO DO AND OTHERS
NEEDED THEM MORE.
AND THEN THERE WERE THE SCENES
OF THE SCHOOL CHILDREN HELPING
ONE ANOTHER, HOLDING EACH OTHER,
DUTIFULLY FOLLOWING INSTRUCTIONS
IN THE WAY THAT YOUNG CHILDREN
SOMETIMES DO.
ONE CHILD EVEN TRYING TO
ENCOURAGE A GROWNUP BY SAYING,
"I KNOW KARATE, SO IT'S OKAY,
I'LL LEAD THE WAY OUT."
AS A COMMUNITY, YOU'VE INSPIRED
US, NEWTOWN.
IN THE FACE OF INDESCRIBABLE
VIOLENCE, IN THE FACE OF
UNCONSCIONABLE EVIL, YOU'VE
LOOKED OUT FOR EACH OTHER.
YOU'VE CARED FOR ONE ANOTHER.
AND YOU'VE LOVED ONE ANOTHER.
THIS IS HOW NEWTOWN WILL BE
REMEMBERED, AND WITH TIME AND
GOD'S GRACE, THAT LOVE WILL SEE
YOU THROUGH.
BUT WE AS A NATION, WE ARE LEFT
WITH SOME HARD QUESTIONS.
SOMEONE ONCE DESCRIBED THE JOY
AND ANXIETY OF PARENTHOOD AS THE
EQUIVALENT OF HAVING YOUR HEART
OUTSIDE OF YOUR BODY ALL THE
TIME, WALKING AROUND.
WITH THEIR VERY FIRST CRY, THIS
MOST PRECIOUS, VITAL PART OF
OURSELVES, OUR CHILD.
SUDDENLY EXPOSED TO THE WORLD
THE POSSIBLE MISHAP OR MALICE,
AND EVERY PARENT KNOWS THERE'S
NOTHING WE WILL NOT DO TO SHIELD
OUR CHILDREN FROM HARM, AND YET
WE ALSO KNOW THAT WITH THAT
CHILD'S VERY FIRST STEP AND EACH
STEP AFTER THAT, THEY ARE
SEPARATING FROM US.
THAT WE WON'T -- THAT WE CAN'T
ALWAYS BE THERE FOR THEM.
THEY WILL SUFFER SICKNESS AND
SETBACKS AND BROKEN HEARTS AND
DISAPPOINTMENTS, AND WE LEARN
THAT OUR MOST IMPORTANT JOB IS
TO GIVE THEM WHAT THEY NEED TO
BECOME SELF RELIANT AND CAPABLE
AND RESILIENT, READY TO FACE THE
WORLD WITHOUT FEAR.
AND WE KNOW WE CAN'T DO THIS BY
OURSELVES.
IT COMES AS A SHOCK AT A CERTAIN
POINT WHERE YOU REALIZE NO
MATTER HOW MUCH YOU LOVE THESE
KIDS, YOU CAN'T DO IT BY
YOURSELF.
THAT THIS JOB OF KEEPING OUR
CHILDREN SAFE AND TEACHING THEM
WELL IS SOMETHING WE CAN ONLY DO
TOGETHER.
WITH THE HELP OF FRIENDS AND
NEIGHBORS, THE HELP OF A
COMMUNITY AND THE HELP OF A
NATION.
AND IN THAT WAY WE COME TO
REALIZE THAT WE BEAR
RESPONSIBILITY FOR EVERY CHILD,
BECAUSE WE'RE COUNTING ON
EVERYBODY ELSE TO HELP LOOK
AFTER OURS.
THAT WE'RE ALL PARENTS, THAT
THEY ARE ALL OUR CHILDREN.
THIS IS OUR FIRST TASK, CARING
FOR OUR CHILDREN.
OUR FIRST JOB.
IF WE DON'T GET THAT RIGHT, WE
DON'T GET ANYTHING RIGHT.
THAT'S HOW, AS A SOCIETY, WE
WILL BE JUDGED.
AND BY THAT MEASURE, CAN WE
TRULY SAY, AS A NATION, THAT
WE'RE MEETING OUR OBLIGATIONS?
CAN WE HONESTLY SAY THAT WE'RE
DOING ENOUGH TO KEEP OUR
CHILDREN, ALL OF THEM, SAFE FROM
HARM?
CAN WE CLAIM, AS A NATION, THAT
WE'RE ALL TOGETHER THERE,
LETTING THEM KNOW THEY ARE LOVED
AND TEACHING THEM TO LOVE IN
RETURN?
CAN WE SAY THAT WE'RE TRULY
DOING ENOUGH TO GIVE ALL THE
CHILDREN OF THIS COUNTRY THE
CHANCE THEY DESERVE TO LIVE OUR
THEIR LIVES IN HAPPINESS AND
WITH PURPOSE?
I'VE BEEN REFLECTING ON THIS THE
LAST FEW DAYS, AND IF WE'RE
HONEST WITH OURSELVES, THE
ANSWER'S NO.
WE'RE NOT DOING ENOUGH.
AND WE WILL HAVE TO CHANGE.
SINCE I'VE BEEN PRESIDENT, THIS
IS THE FOURTH TIME WE HAVE COME
TOGETHER TO COMFORT A GRIEVING
COMMUNITY TORN APART BY MASS
SHOOTINGS.
FOURTH TIME WE'VE HUGGED
SURVIVORS, THE FOURTH TIME WE'VE
CONSOLED THE FAMILIES OF
VICTIMS, AND IN BETWEEN, THERE
HAVE BEEN AN ENDLESS SERIES OF
DEADLY SHOOTINGS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY, DAILY REPORTS OF
VICTIMS, MANY OF THEM CHILDREN,
IN SMALL TOWNS AND CITIES ALL
ACROSS AMERICA.
VICTIMS WHO MUCH OF THE TIME
THEIR ONLY FAULT WAS BEING AT
THE WRONG PLACE AT THE WRONG
TIME.
WE CAN'T TOLERATE THIS ANYMORE.
THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
AND TO END THEM, WE MUST CHANGE.
WE WILL BE TOLD THAT THE CAUSES
OF SUCH VIOLENCE ARE COMPLEXED,
AND THAT IS TRUE.
NO SINGLE LAW, NO SET OF LAWS
CAN ELIMINATE EVIL FROM THE
WORLD OR PREVENT EVERY SENSELESS
ACT OF VIOLENCE IN OUR SOCIETY,
BUT THAT CAN'T BE AN EXCUSE FOR
AN ACTION.
SURELY WE CAN DO BETTER THAN
THIS.
IF THERE'S EVEN ONE STEP WE CAN
TAKE TO SAVE ANOTHER CHILD OR
ANOTHER PARENT OR ANOTHER TOWN
FROM THE GRIEF THAT'S VISITED
TUCSON AND AURORA AND OAK CREEK
AND NEWTOWN AND COMMUNITIES FROM
COLUMBINE TO BLACKSBURG BEFORE
THAT, THEN SURELY WE HAVE AN
OBLIGATION TO TRY.
IN THE COMING WEEKS, I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS,
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT, TO MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS, TO PARENTS
WE CAN'T ACCEPT EVENTS LIKE THIS
AS ROUTINE.
ARE WE REALLY PREPARED TO SAY
THAT WE'RE POWERLESS IN THE FACE
OF SUCH CARNAGE?
THAT THE POLITICS ARE TOO HARD.
ARE WE PREPARED TO SAY THAT SUCH
VIOLENCE VISITED ON OUR CHILDREN
YEAR AFTER YEAR AFTER YEAR IS
SOMEHOW THE PRICE OF OUR
FREEDOM?
YOU KNOW, ALL THE WORLD'S
RELIGIONS, SO MANY OF THEM
REPRESENTED HERE TODAY, START
WITH A SIMPLE QUESTION.
WHY ARE WE HERE?
WHAT GIVES OUR LIFE MEANING?
WHAT GIVES OUR ACTS PURPOSE?
WE KNOW OUR TIME ON THIS EARTH
IS FLEETING.
WE KNOW THAT WE WILL EACH HAVE
OUR SHARE OF PLEASURE AND PAIN,
THAT EVEN AFTER WE CHASE AFTER
SOME EARTHLY GOAL, WHETHER IT'S
WEALTH OR POWER OR FAME OR JUST
SIMPLE COMFORT, WE WILL, IN SOME
FASHION, FALL SHORT OF WHAT WE
HAD HOPED.
WE KNOW THAT NO MATTER HOW GOOD
OUR INTENTIONS, WE'LL ALL
STUMBLE SOMETIMES IN SOME WAY.
WE'LL MAKE MISTAKES, WE'LL
EXPERIENCE HARDSHIPS, AND EVEN
WHEN WE'RE TRYING TO DO THE
RIGHT THING, WE KNOW THAT MUCH
OF OUR TIME WILL BE SPENT
GROPING THROUGH THE DARKNESS, SO
OFTEN UNABLE TO DISCERN GOD'S
HEAVENLY PLANS.
THERE'S ONLY ONE THING WE CAN BE
SURE OF, AND THAT IS THE LOVE
THAT WE HAVE.
FOR OUR CHILDREN, FOR OUR
FAMILIES, FOR EACH OTHER.
THE WARMTH OF A SMALL CHILD'S
EMBRACE, THAT IS TRUE.
THE MEMORIES WE HAVE OF THEM,
THE JOY THAT THEY BRING, THE
WONDER WE SEE THROUGH THEIR
EYES, THAT FIERCE AND BOUNDLESS
LOVE WE FEEL FOR THEM, A LOVE
THAT TAKES US OUT OF OURSELVES
AND BINDS US TO SOMETHING
LARGER.
WE KNOW THAT'S WHAT MATTERS.
WE KNOW WE'RE ALWAYS DOING RIGHT
WHEN WE'RE TAKING CARE OF THEM.
WHEN WE'RE TEACHING THEM WELL.
WHEN WE'RE SHOWING ACTS OF
KINDNESS.
WE DON'T GO WRONG WHEN WE DO
THAT.
THAT'S WHAT WE CAN BE SURE OF,
AND THAT'S WHAT YOU, THE PEOPLE
OF NEWTOWN, HAVE REMINDED US.
THAT'S HOW YOU'VE INSPIRED US.
YOU REMIND US WHAT MATTERS.
AND THAT'S WHAT SHOULD DRIVE US
FORWARD IN EVERYTHING WE DO FOR
AS LONG AS GOD SEES FIT TO KEEP
US ON THIS EARTH.
LET THE LITTLE CHILDREN COME TO
ME, JESUS SAID, AND DO NOT
HINDER THEM, FOR TO SUCH BELONGS
THE KINGDOM OF HEAVEN.
CHARLOTTE, DANIEL, OLIVIA,
JOSEPHINE, ANA, DYLAN,
MADELEINE, CATHERINE, CHASE,
JESSE, JAMES, GRACE, EMILIE,
JACK, NOAH, CAROLINE, JESSICA,
BENJAMIN, AVIELLE, ALLISON.
GOD HAS CALLED THEM ALL HOME.
FOR THOSE OF US WHO REMAIN, LET
US FIND THE STRENGTH TO CARRY ON
AND MAKE OUR COUNTRY WORTHY OF
THEIR MEMORY.
MAY GOD BLESS AND KEEP THOSE
WE'VE LOST IN HIS HEAVENLY
PLACE.
MAY HE GRACE THOSE WE STILL HAVE
WITH HIS HOLY COMFORT, AND MAY
HE BLESS AND WATCH OVER THIS
COMMUNITY AND THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> ON BEHALF OF THE NEWTOWN
CLERGY ASSOCIATION, WE ARE SO
GRATEFUL TO OUR PRESIDENT FOR
SPENDING TIME WITH US AND FOR
REMINDING US THAT WE ARE NOT
ALONE IN THIS TIME OF TRAGEDY,
THAT THERE'S NOT JUST A COUNTRY
STANDING BEHIND US, THAT THERE'S
A WORLD STANDING BEHIND US.
THOSE WORDS I KNOW AS DIFFICULT
AS THEY WERE TO HEAR FOR SOME,
BROUGHT MUCH CONSOLATION TO ALL.
I WANT TO THANK OUR GOVERNOR AND
ALL THE STATE OFFICIALS WHO HAVE
BEEN BY OUR SIDE SINCE DAY ONE.
THEY HAVE BEEN A REMARKABLE
REMINDER TO US OF THEIR HUMANITY
AND THEIR CARE FOR US.
BUT MOST OF ALL, I WANT TO THANK
AN INCREDIBLE FIRST-SELECT WOMAN
WHO'S LED US THROUGH THE MOST
DARK PERIODS OF OUR LIVES.
IN THE STORMS OF THE PAST YEARS
RAVAGED OUR COMMUNITY WITHOUT
POWER FOR DAYS, I THOUGHT THOSE
WERE THE HARDEST DAYS OF PAT'S
LIFE, BUT WHEN I SAW HER FRIDAY
IN FRONT OF SANDY HOOK SCHOOL, I
REALIZED THAT SHE'D MET THE MOST
DARK DAYS.
PAT, TO YOU, TO DR. ROBINSON, WE
THANK YOU FOR BEING LEADERS TO
US THROUGH THESE DIFFICULT
TIMES.
AND NOW THIS FINAL PART OF OUR
PRAYER IS FOR US, THE PEOPLE OF
NEWTOWN.
>> THESE ARE THE WORDS OF THE
APOSTLE PAUL AS HE WRITES TO THE
CHURCH AT ROME.
WHAT THEN SHALL WE SAY IN
RESPONSE TO THIS, IF GOD IS FOR
US, WHO CAN BE AGAINST US?
HE WHO DID NOT SPARE HIS OWN
SON, BUT GAVE HIM UP FOR ALL OF
US, HOW WILL HE NOT ALSO ALONG
WITH HIM GRACIOUSLY GIVE US ALL
THINGS?
WHO WILL BRING ANY CHARGE
AGAINST THOSE WHOM GOD HAS
CHOSEN, THAT IS GOD WHO
JUSTIFIES, WHO IS HE THAT
CONDEMNS?
CHRIST JESUS WHO DIED, MORE THAN
THAT WHO WAS RAISED TO LIFE, WAS
AT THE RIGHT HAND OF GOD AND IS
ALSO INTERCEDING FOR US.
WHO SHALL SEPARATE US FROM THE
LOVE OF CHRIST, SHALL TROUBLE OR
HARDSHIP OR PERSECUTION OR
FAMINE OR NAKEDNESS OR DANGER OR
SWORD AS IT IS WRITTEN FOR YOUR
SAKE, WE FACE DEATH ALL DAY
LONG, WE ARE CONSIDERED AS SHEEP
TO BE SLAUGHTERED.
KNOW IN ALL THESE THINGS WE ARE
MORE THAN CONQUERERS THROUGH HIM
WHO LOVED US, FOR I AM CONVINCED
THAT NEITHER DEATH, NOR LIFE,
NEITHER ANGELS, NOR DEMONS,
NEITHER THE PRESENCE, NOR THE
FUTURE, NEITHER ANY POWERS,
HEIGHT, NOR DEPTH, IN ALL
CREATION WILL BE ABLE TO
SEPARATE US FROM THE LOVE OF GOD
THAT IS IN CHRIST JESUS OUR
LORD.
>> AND SO WE STAND NOW IN PRAYER
FOR OURSELVES.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN, BUT OUR
SPIRITS ARE STRENGTHENED BY THE
POWER OF GOD'S GOODNESS AND HIS
EVER-CREATING LOVE AND BY THE
GENEROUS HEARTS OF A COMMUNITY
WHO TRULY CARES.
WE HAVE SHOWN TO THE WORLD OUR
COMPASSION.
BUT YOU HAVE PLACED ON OUR
SHOULDERS A BURDEN OF IMAGINABLE
PAIN.
YOU HAVE PUT IN OUR HEARTS THE
RESOLVE TO WORK TOGETHER TO MAKE
OF THIS WORLD A PLACE OF
JUSTICE, OF PEACE, OF TRUTH, FOR
OUR PEOPLE, ESPECIALLY FOR OUR
YOUNG.
WE THANK YOU THIS NIGHT FOR OUR
COMMUNITY LEADERS WHO HAVE
WALKED A DARK ROAD HELPING US
FIND A LIGHT.
WE PRAY FOR MEN AND FOR WOMEN
AND WHOSE LOVE FOR EACH OTHER
HAS GIVEN US CHILDREN THAT WE
MIGHT GUIDE AND ENCOURAGE THEM.
WE SEEK YOUR WISDOM AS OUR
ADMINISTRATORS AND OUR EDUCATORS
CONTINUE TO TEACH OUR CHILDREN
WAYS TO STRENGTHEN THEM TO BE
PRODUCTIVE AND POSITIVE CITIZENS
OF THIS WORLD, TO ONLY BRING
RIGHT AND GOOD, NOT HARM OR
HURT.
WE PRAY THAT THIS CULTURE OF
DEATH THAT IS OVERSHADOWING OUR
ENTIRE COUNTRY, ESPECIALLY NOW
IN THIS, OUR TOWN, WILL SOON BE
REPLACED WITH A CULTURE OF LIFE
THAT EMBRACES EVERY PERSON WITH
HUMAN DIGNITY.
WE ARE BROUGHT TO YOU TONIGHT IN
OUR PRAYER THOSE WE HAVE LOST,
THOSE WHOSE HEARTS HAVE BEEN
BROKEN FOREVER.
WE BRING TO YOU 20 NEW STARS IN
THE HEAVENS, 20 NEW SAINTS, 20
NEW ANGELS.
WE BRING TO YOU THOSE WHO RISKED
THEIR LIVES FOR US EVERY DAY,
NOT COUNTING THE COST.
AND WE BRING TO YOU THOSE WHO
GUIDE, THOSE WHO COUNSEL, THOSE
WHO BLESS AND EMBRACE THE
CONFUSED AND THE BROKEN.
AND NOW IN THIS PRAYER WE BRING
TO YOU OURSELVES, OUR
BROKENNESS, OUR QUESTIONS, OUR
DOUBTS, OUR ANGER, AND OUR
HEARTS.
AND WE PRAY FOR THE PEACE, THE
HOPE, AND THE RENEWAL OF TRUST
THAT CAN COME ONLY FROM A GOD
WHO FIRST CONCEIVED US IN LOVE
AND PLACED A HAND OF COMPASSION
ON EACH OF OUR SHOULDERS, EVEN
IN THIS MOST CHALLENGING TIME.
AND SO TONIGHT, FOR OUR
COMMUNITY, A COMMUNITY DEEPLY
PAINED, WE ASK YOU TO HEAL THE
BROKENNESS, TO ANSWER OUR
QUESTIONS, TO REPLACE OUR DOUBTS
WITH CERTAINTY, OUR ANGER WITH
PEACE, AND OUR HURT WITH
HEALING.
GOD, WE THANK YOU FOR THIS TOWN.
WE THANK YOU FOR ITS PEOPLE.
AND WE THANK YOU FOR THIS
OPPORTUNITY TO STAND TOGETHER
AND NOT TO FALL APART.
AMEN.
>> NOW A FINAL BLESSING OF HOPE
THROUGH FAITH IN JESUS CHRIST
FROM THE WORDS OF ST. JOHN AND
SAINT PAUL.
I HEARD A LOUD VOICE FROM THE
THRONE SAYING, BEHOLD THE
DWELLING PLACE OF GOD IS WITH
MAN.
HE WILL DWELL WITH THEM AND THEY
WILL BE HIS PEOPLE AND GOD
HIMSELF WILL BE WITH THEM AS
THEIR GOD.
HE WILL WIPE AWAY EVERY TEAR
FROM THEIR EYES AND DEAF SHALL
BE NO MORE.
NEITHER SHALL THERE BE MOURNING,
NOR CRYING, NOR PAIN ANYMORE,
FOR THE FORMER THINGS HAVE
PASSED AWAY, AND HE WHO WAS
SEATED ON THE THRONE SAID,
BEHOLD I AM MAKING ALL THINGS
NEW.
AND NOW, MAY THE GRACE OF OUR
LORD JESUS CHRIST AND THE LOVE
OF GOD AND THE COMMUNION OF THE
HOLY SPIRIT BE WITH YOU ALL.
AMEN.
I ASK YOU TO PLEASE TAKE YOUR
SEATS UNTIL I CAN RECEIVE
CONFIRMATION THAT THE PRESIDENT
HAS SAFELY EXITED THE SCHOOL
CAMPUS.
AND I DON'T KNOW WHO THAT
CONFIRMATION IS GOING TO COME
FROM.
BUT ALLOW ME TO SAY WHILE I WAIT
FOR THAT, WE THEN ENCOURAGE ALL
OF YOU, ON BEHALF OF THE NEWTOWN
CLERGY, GIVE TO ONE ANOTHER ALL
THE LOVE AND CARE AND SUPPORT
THAT YOU CAN.
AND CLERGY WILL BE AVAILABLE FOR
YOU AT THIS TIME AT THE PLATFORM
FOR A TIME OF PRAYER, ACCORDING
TO EACH OF THEIR TEACHINGS AND
BELIEFS.
SO PLEASE DO REMAIN SEATED UNTIL
I RECEIVE THAT WORD OF
CONFIRMATION AND THEN COMFORT
ONE ANOTHER.
>> A POWERFUL, VERY MOVING
INTERFAITH PRAYER VIGIL HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE HEARD FROM THE CLERGY, FROM
VARIOUS RELIGIONS, RELIGIONS OF
THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA.
WE HEARD, OF COURSE, FROM THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES,
AND HE VOWED AFTER THE SENSELESS
MURDERS IN ARIZONA, IN COLORADO,
IN WISCONSIN, AND NOW HERE IN
CONNECTICUT, HE VOWED THAT HE
WOULD DO WHATEVER HIS OFFICE
WOULD ALLOW HIM TO DO, WHATEVER
POWERS HE NOW HAS, TO TRY TO
MAKE SURE THIS DOES NOT HAPPEN
AGAIN.
AND HE WILL WORK DILIGENTLY IN
THAT AREA.
ANDERSON COOPER, WE WATCHED
THESE FAITHS, THEY WERE WELL
REPRESENTATIVE.
WE CAN ONLY HOPE AND PRAY THAT
THOSE WHO NOW MOURN WILL GET AT
LEAST A LITTLE BIT OF COMFORT
FROM WHAT WE JUST SAW.
>> AND THE PRESIDENT TOWARD THE
END OF HIS REMARKS ASKING IF WE
ARE, ALL OF US AS A SOCIETY,
DOING ALL WE CAN TO PROTECT OUR
CHILDREN.
HE SAID HE FELT WE ARE NOT AND
HE SAID WE CAN DO BETTER.
VERY POWERFUL WORDS FROM
PRESIDENT OBAMA ENDING THIS
CEREMONY, AND NOW PEOPLE IN THE
AUDIENCE GREETING ONE ANOTHER,
HUGGING ONE ANOTHER.
FIRST RESPONDERS ARE STILL
INSIDE.
WOLF, VERY MOVING MOMENT WHEN
THE FIRST RESPONDERS CAME INTO
THE ROOM SHORTLY BEFORE THE
SERVICE BEGAN, THERE WAS A
STANDING OVATION FOR THEM.
NO DOUBT MANY PEOPLE NOW
APPROACHING THOSE FIRST
RESPONDERS, JUST WANTING TO
THANK THEM, SHAKE THEIR HAND,
HUG THEM, PERHAPS SHARE A TEAR
WITH THEM.
A LOT OF PEOPLE WHO WERE
WATCHING IN OVERFLOW ROOMS AND
OUTSIDE HUDDLED UNDER BLANKETS
GIVEN BY THE RED CROSS ARE
SLOWLY WALKING AWAY, PAST THE
LOCATION WHERE WE ARE, PAST A
MAKESHIFT MEMORIAL, WHICH IS
OUTSIDE THE HIGH SCHOOL, PAUSING
FOR A MOMENT.
SOME CARRYING CANDLES.
SOME DEPOSITING THOSE CANDLES
DOWN ON THE GROUND, SLOWLY
WALKING BACK TO THEIR CARS WITH
THEIR FAMILIES.
THIS HAS BEEN A VERY MOVING
SERVICE HEARING FROM, AS YOU
SAID, A NUMBER OF DENOMINATIONS,
FROM PASTORS, WE HEARD FROM A
RABBI, AS WELL AS A
REPRESENTATIVE OF THE MUSLIM
COMMUNITY SINGING.
OVERALL, VERY MOVING CEREMONY.
DON LEMON IS STANDING BY.
HE'S BEEN TALKING WITH PEOPLE
WHO HAVE BEEN WATCHING THE
SERVICE, WHO HAVE BEEN STOPPING
BY THE MAKESHIFT MEMORIAL ALL
EVENING LONG.
DON, WHAT HAVE YOU BEEN HEARING
FROM PEOPLE?
>> Reporter: I'VE BEEN HEARING A
LOT.
PEOPLE, OF COURSE, COMING BY TO
LIGHT CANDLES AND DROP THINGS
OFF, ANDERSON.
SOME WERE STANDING OUT HERE
WATCHING THE MEMORIAL ON THEIR
SMARTPHONES ON CNN AND THE STONE
RIVER GRILL, A TAVERN ACROSS THE
STREET THEY WERE WATCHING.
YOU CAN SEE THERE'S A BAND HERE
THAT SAYS, "REMEMBER THE
CHILDREN."
THEY WALKED BY.
THEY HAD BEEN PLAYING AND
WALKING UP AND DOWN THE STREET
HERE.
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN HUGGING EACH
OTHER.
THEY HAVE BEEN CRYING, THEY HAVE
BEEN COMFORTING EACH OTHER.
THE PEOPLE WHO ARE WATCHING IN
THE TAVERN ACROSS THE STREET
AFTER THE PRESIDENT SPOKE CAME
OUT TO TALK.
SOME PEOPLE WERE WATCHING IN
RESTAURANTS.
CHRIS, YOU WERE WATCHING AS
WELL.
THE PRESIDENT OFFER ANY WORDS OF
COMFORT TO YOU?
>> YEAH, I THINK HE -- WHAT HE
SAID THAT WAS COMFORTING IS IT'S
TIME FOR CHANGE AND TIME TO
ACTUALLY DO SOMETHING ABOUT ALL
THE VIOLENCE WE'VE BEEN HAVING
LATELY IN THIS COUNTRY.
>> Reporter: AND YOU KNOW THAT
VIOLENCE.
>> YEAH, I HAD A SON THAT WAS
MURDERED FIVE AND A HALF YEARS
AGO, SO THIS DEFINITELY STIRS UP
A LOT OF THOSE EMOTIONS FOR ME,
ABSOLUTELY, WITH ALL THE LITTLE
INNOCENT CHILDREN THAT DIED.
>> Reporter: TO SEE THIS
MEMORIAL AND TO SEE THE PEOPLE
ALL COMING TOGETHER, DOES THAT
COMFORT YOU AT ALL TO THE PEOPLE
IN THE COMMUNITY?
>> IT DOES.
IT'S A WONDERFUL AREA.
PEOPLE IN NEWTOWN ARE BEAUTIFUL
PEOPLE.
I THINK IT'S -- I THINK THE WAY
PEOPLE ARE JUST BONDING
TOGETHER, IT SAYS A LOT ABOUT
THIS COMMUNITY, JUST THIS PART
OF THE COUNTRY.
>> Reporter: THANK YOU.
THERE ARE PEOPLE HERE THAT ARE
HANGING JAPANESE BIRDS OVER HERE
THAT THEY SAID THAT THEY'D HAD
DURING THEIR WEDDING.
1,000 WISHES, THEY SAY, FOR
EVERYONE INVOLVED IN THIS.
OTHER FOLKS COMING REALLY FROM
ALL AROUND THE AREA JUST TO PAY
THEIR RESPECTS AND TO OFFER
COMFORT TO EACH OTHER HERE AS WE
LISTEN TO THIS BAND AND WE
FINISH UP THE MEMORIAL HERE.
THIS ONE IS TEMPORARY, BUT I'M
SURE A PERMANENT ONE WILL BE
ERECTED, BUT THIS ONE WILL HAVE
TO OFFER COMFORT FOR THE TIME
BEING.
WOLF BLITZER, MOVING CEREMONY BY
THE PRESIDENT, VERY TOUCHING
MOMENT REALLY HERE IN NEWTOWN IN
THE SQUARE WHERE PEOPLE ARE JUST
PAYING THEIR RESPECTS AND LOVING
EACH OTHER.
>> AS THEY SHOULD RIGHT NOW.
I THINK THE WHOLE COUNTRY HAS
BEEN MOVED BY WHAT WE HAVE JUST
SEEN AND WILL REFLECT ON WHAT WE
HAVE JUST SEEN AS WELL.
I WAS ESPECIALLY MOVED AT THE
END WHEN THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES READ THE NAMES OF
THOSE KIDS WHO WERE KILLED
FRIDAY MORNING AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
AND LET'S REMEMBER WHO THESE
PEOPLE WERE.
♪
>> JUST A TRAGIC, TRAGIC
SITUATION FOR THE TEACHERS, THE
PRINCIPALS, AND THOSE ANGELS.
THAT'S ALL I KEEP THINKING ABOUT
IS THOSE ANGELS.
♪
>> I MEAN, WHEN THINGS HAPPEN TO
YOUR CHILDREN, AND TO OTHER
PEOPLE'S CHILDREN, I CAN'T LOOK
AT MY CHILDREN'S FACES NOW
WITHOUT SEEING THE FACES OF
EVERY ONE OF THEIR SCHOOLMATES.
♪
>>> GOOD EVENING, IT'S BEEN AN
INCREDIBLY MOVING VIGIL TONIGHT
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, AS THE
COMMUNITY COMES TOGETHER TO
MOURN ITS LOST CHILDREN AND
TEACHERS.
THIS COUNTRY IS GRIEVING AS
WELL.
VISIBLY EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT
OBAMA MET WITH FAMILIES,
INCLUDING THE BABY GRANDDAUGHTER
OF SLAIN PRINCIPAL DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG, THEN HE SPOKE TO THE
PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN AND THE
NATION, PROMISING TO DO ALL HE
CAN TO PREVENT FURTHER TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS.
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS, I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS,
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT, TO MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS, TO PARENTS
AND EDUCATORS, IN AN EFFORT
AIMED AT PREVENTING MORE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS, BECAUSE
WHAT CHOICE DO WE HAVE?
WE CAN'T ACCEPT EVENTS LIKE THIS
AS ROUTINE.
ARE WE REALLY PREPARED TO SAY
THAT WE'RE POWERLESS IN THE FACE
OF SUCH CARNAGE?
>> IN THE MIDST OF HIS ALMOST
INCOMPREHENSIBLE TRAGEDY, THERE
WERE HEROS, ONE OF THEM, VICKI
SOTO, A 27-YEAR-OLD TEACHER,
GAVE HER LIFE TO PROTECT HER
STUDENTS.
JOINING ME NOW, VICKI'S SISTER,
BROTHER, COUSIN, WELCOME TO YOU
ALL.
IT'S BEEN AN INCREDIBLY MOVING
DAY, AGAIN, IN NEWTOWN.
AND THE WORDS OF THE PRESIDENT
IN PARTICULAR THIS EVENING, VERY
CONTROLLED ANGER, HE WANTS TO
TRY TO DO SOMETHING, ANYTHING,
TO STOP THIS HAPPENING AGAIN.
THE APPALLING TRAGEDY, WHICH HAS
EFFECTED SO MANY FAMILIES,
INCLUDING YOUR OWN.
IF I MAY START WITH YOU, DONNA,
VICKI WAS YOUR DAUGHTER, SHE WAS
27.
THERE HAVE BEEN SO MANY TRIBUTES
TO HER PAID BY SO MANY PEOPLE.
WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE TO SAY?
>> I'D JUST LIKE EVERYONE TO
KNOW THAT SHE WAS JUST A
BEAUTIFUL, BEAUTIFUL YOUNG LADY.
SHE HAD SUCH PASSION FOR
TEACHING AND FOR LIFE AND
ESPECIALLY FOR HER FAMILY.
SHE WAS EXTREMELY CLOSE TO HER
SIBLINGS THAT ARE SITTING WITH
ME, HER COUSINS, AND LOVED THEM
DEARLY.
AND WANTED TO BE A TEACHER FROM
THE TIME SHE WAS 3.
THAT'S ALL SHE EVER WANTED TO
DO.
SHE JUST LOVED HER KIDS.
SHE JUST TALKED ABOUT THEM ALL
THE TIME WITH SUCH FONDNESS AND
CARING, AND SHE JUST ADORED
THEM.
AND I HAVE NO DOUBT IN MY MIND
SHE DID EVERYTHING SHE COULD TO
PROTECT EVERY SINGLE ONE OF
THEM.
>> WHAT SHE DID WAS INCREDIBLY
HEROIC, AND SHE SAVED MANY LIVES
WITH HER ACTIONS.
KNOWING HER, AS HER MOTHER, AS
WELL AS ANYBODY IN THE WORLD
KNEW HER, DID IT SURPRISE YOU
THAT SHE WAS SO COURAGEOUS IN
SUCH A TERRIFYING MOMENT?
>> NOT AT ALL.
SHE WAS TRULY SELFLESS.
SHE WOULD NOT HESITATE TO THINK
TO SAVE ANYONE ELSE BEFORE
HERSELF, AND ESPECIALLY
CHILDREN.
SHE LOVED THEM MORE THAN LIFE,
AND SHE WOULD DEFINITELY PUT
HERSELF IN FRONT OF THEM ANY
DAY, ANY DAY AND FOR ANY REASON.
IT DOESN'T SURPRISE ANYBODY THAT
KNOWS VICKI THAT SHE DID THIS.
>> CARLY, VICKI WAS YOUR SISTER,
YOU WERE ALL VERY CLOSE, AS YOUR
MOTHER JUST SAID.
IT'S OBVIOUSLY A TERRIBLE,
TORRENTIAL LOSS, YOU MUST BE
GRIEVING HORRIBLY, YET AT THE
SAME TIME HEARING THE PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED STATES TALK ABOUT
YOUR SISTER AS A HERO, IT MUST
HAVE BEEN VERY MOVING TO YOU.
>> IT WAS VERY MUCH.
I APPRECIATE ALL HIS KIND WORDS
THAT HE DID SAY ABOUT MY SISTER.
SHE WAS A HERO, AND SHE STILL
IS.
>> WHAT KIND OF PERSON WAS SHE,
CARLEE?
>> SHE WAS SO CARING.
SHE PUT ANYBODY ELSE BEFORE HER.
SHE WANTED THE BEST FOR
EVERYONE.
SHE JUST LOVED LIFE, AND SHE
LOVED TEACHING.
>> AND JILLIAN, YOU'RE ALL
WEARING GREEN BECAUSE THAT WAS
VICKI'S FAVORITE COLOR, AND I
HEARD YOU SAY THIS MORNING THAT
WHEN IT SNOWED, YOU FELT IT WAS
IN SOME WAY A SIGNAL FROM YOUR
SISTER.
>> IT WAS.
IT'S LIKE HER LOOKING DOWN AT US
AND LETTING US KNOW THAT SHE'S
HERE WITH US AND SHE LOVED THE
CHRISTMAS HOLIDAY.
SHE LOVED EVERYTHING ABOUT IT,
THE SNOW THAT COMES WITH IT, SO
WHEN IT STARTED TO HAIL, THE
THREE OF US KNEW IT WAS OUR
SISTER SAYING THAT I'M HERE WITH
YOU GUYS, EVEN THROUGH ALL OF
THIS.
GREEN IS HER FAVORITE COLOR.
>> I'M SORRY.
>> WE JUST WANTED TO WEAR THE
GREEN TO SHOW HOW MUCH WE LOVE
HER AND HONOR HER FOR IT.
>> CARLOS, YOU WERE VICKI'S
BROTHER.
WHEN YOU HEARD WHAT HAD HAPPENED
AT THE SCHOOL, IT MUST HAVE
BEEN, I IMAGINE, THE WORST
MOMENT OF YOUR LIFE.
TRY AND SUM UP FOR ME WHAT IT'S
BEEN LIKE FOR YOU AS A FAMILY
SINCE THIS DREADFUL, DREADFUL
MOMENT HAPPENED.
>> IT'S JUST BEEN HORRIBLE.
THERE'S BEEN SO MANY PEOPLE HERE
TO SUPPORT US, AND I REALLY
THINK THAT SHE WANTED US TO COME
BACK TOGETHER.
AND WE'VE ALWAYS BEEN CLOSE, BUT
SHE'S JUST GOING TO BRING US
CLOSER, AND I KNOW WE'LL ALWAYS
REMEMBER HER FOR THIS.
>> AND CARLOS, HOW DO YOU FEEL
ABOUT THE WAY THE COMMUNITY HAS
RALLIED TOGETHER?
THE PRESIDENT NOTICED THIS,
YOU'VE COME TOGETHER AS A
COMMUNITY, NOT JUST THOSE WHO
HAVE LOST PEOPLE, BUT JUST THE
WHOLE COMMUNITY.
AND YOU'VE BEEN JOINED BY
AMERICA, I THINK, THAT'S BEEN
SHATTERED BY WHAT'S HAPPENED,
FROM THE PRESIDENT DOWN.
WHAT DO YOU THINK WILL HAPPEN
WITH NEWTOWN NOW?
HOW WILL THEY RECOVER FROM THIS?
>> I DON'T THINK IT WILL EVER BE
A FULL RECOVERY.
I KNOW THAT THESE 27 PEOPLE THAT
LOST THEIR LIVES WILL BE
REMEMBERED AND WILL BE MISSED TO
THE FULLEST, AND I JUST -- IT'S
JUST SO THANKFUL TO KNOW THAT
EVERYONE IN STRATFORD HAS BEEN
TOUCHED BY HER LIFE SOMEHOW AND
CAME HERE TO CELEBRATE HER LIFE.
>> I UNDERSTAND, DONNA, THAT
CARLEE MET WITH THE PRESIDENT
TODAY.
CAN YOU TALK ABOUT THAT?
>> WE ALL MET WITH THE PRESIDENT
TODAY.
IT WAS -- HE WAS VERY, VERY
CARING AND VERY SUPPORTIVE AND
TOLD US HE KNEW ALL ABOUT VICKI
AND WHAT SHE DID AND WHAT A HERO
SHE WAS.
AND SHE WAS JUST VERY, VERY KIND
TO US AND GAVE US THE TIME WE
NEEDED WITH HIM, AND IT WAS --
IT WAS VERY COMFORTING.
>> AND JAMES, YOU WERE VICKI'S
COUSIN, YOU'RE ALSO A POLICE
OFFICER.
IT WAS VERY NOTICEABLE IN THE
PRESIDENT'S SPEECH TONIGHT THAT
HE SEEMS, ALTHOUGH HE NEVER
MENTIONED THE WORD GUNS, HE'S
DETERMINED TO DO WHATEVER HE
CAN, HE SAID, TO TRY AND PREVENT
ANOTHER SHOOTING TRAGEDY LIKE
THIS.
AND MANY ARE TAKING THIS TO MEAN
GUN CONTROL, WHATEVER IT MAY BE.
WHAT WAS YOUR REACTION AS A
POLICEMAN TO WHAT HE WAS SAYING
THERE?
>> I GOT TO BE HONEST, I DIDN'T
SEE OR HEAR HIS SPEECH YET.
WE -- AFTER WE MET WITH HIM, HE
WAS JUST LOVE AND SUPPORT FROM
HIM WAS COMFORTING FOR THE
FAMILY.
I GOT THE FAMILY BACK HERE TO
STRATFORD.
TO TRY AND ANSWER YOUR QUESTION,
JUST AS ANY OTHER ISSUE, I WOULD
HAVE TO SAY AWARENESS,
AWARENESS, AWARENESS.
FRIENDS, FAMILY, GUN SUPPORTERS,
PEOPLE THAT OPPOSE GUNS, JUST
AWARENESS.
AND BEING AWARE OF YOUR
SURROUNDINGS.
>> I WANT TO THANK YOU ALL FOR
--
>> I DON'T KNOW WHAT ELSE TO
SAY.
>> LISTEN, I DON'T WANT TO PRESS
YOU ON THIS.
IT'S NOT THE TIME FOR YOU AS A
FAMILY TO CONSIDER THESE THINGS.
IT WILL BE FOR THE PRESIDENT AND
POLITICIANS, I THINK, TO DO WHAT
NEEDS TO BE DONE.
THANK YOU ALL VERY MUCH FOR
TAKING THE TIME TO JOIN ME THIS
EVENING AND JUST TO SEND YOU ON
BEHALF OF EVERYONE AT CNN AND
AMERICA THAT'S BEEN THINKING OF
YOU AND YOUR FAMILY.
VICKI WAS A HEROINE, TRUE
AMERICAN, YOUR LOSS IS APPALLING
BUT HER LEGACY AND MEMORY WILL
LIVE ON FOR A VERY, VERY LONG
TIME.
THANK YOU ALL VERY MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
>> BRAVE FAMILY.
I WANT TO BRING YOU WOLF
BLITZER, WHO'S ON THE SCENE OF
TONIGHT'S VIGIL.
WOLF, IT'S A PRETTY UNBEARABLE
STORY, THIS, TO COVER.
YOU CAN ONLY BEGIN TO IMAGINE
WHAT ON EARTH THESE FAMILIES ARE
GOING THROUGH.
WHAT DID YOU MAKE OF THE
PRESIDENT'S SPEECH TONIGHT?
VERY EMOTIONAL, PRETTY
DETERMINED, AND ALTHOUGH HE
DIDN'T MENTION THE WORD GUNS,
PRETTY OBVIOUS, I THINK, HE'S
GOING TO TRY TO DO SOMETHING
FAIRLY DRAMATIC TO TRY AND DO
SOMETHING, AS HE PUT IT, DOING
NOTHING IS NOT AN OPTION
ANYMORE.
>> Reporter: HE SAYS HE'S GOING
TO USE EVERY OPPORTUNITY HE HAS
WITH THE POWER OF HIS OFFICE,
THE PRESIDENCY OF THE UNITED
STATES, TO TRY TO MAKE SURE THIS
DOES NOT HAPPEN AGAIN.
EVEN IF HE CAN SAVE ONE OR TWO
OR THREE YOUNG KIDS, HE WANTS TO
DO IT.
AND IT WAS A CLEAR REFERENCE, I
DON'T THINK THERE'S ANY DOUBT,
PIERS, WHAT THE PRESIDENT WAS
TALKING ABOUT, EVEN THOUGH HE
DIDN'T SAY, FOR EXAMPLE, WE
MUST, YOU KNOW, GET NEW GUN
LEGISLATION TO CONTROL GUNS IN
THE UNITED STATES, THE ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN OR WHATEVER, THAT'S
CLEARLY WHAT HE'S DRIVING AT AND
WHAT HE'S GOING TO TRY TO DO.
WHETHER OR NOT HE SUCCEEDS IS
ANOTHER MANNER.
AS YOU KNOW, THERE'S A LOT OF
OPPOSITION TO A MUCH GREATER GUN
CONTROL IN THIS COUNTRY, BUT I
THINK HE'S GOING TO TRY.
HE DIDN'T TRY DURING THE FIRST
FOUR YEARS.
THERE WERE A LOT OF OTHER ISSUES
ON HIS AGENDA, INCLUDING A U.S.
ECONOMY THAT WAS NEAR, NOT ONLY
RECESSION, BUT POTENTIALLY
ANOTHER DEPRESSION.
A LOT GOING ON, TWO WARS.
BUT RIGHT NOW, HAVING JUST BEEN
REELECTED, HAVING JUST GONE
THROUGH WHAT WE HEARD ONE OF THE
MINISTERS SAY, ONE OF THE PEOPLE
WHO MET WITH HIM, THIS PAST
FRIDAY WHEN HE HEARD ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED AT THAT ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, THE WORST DAY OF
HIS PRESIDENCY, I THINK THERE'S
NO DOUBT HE'S GOING TO TRY TO DO
SOMETHING IN THIS SECOND TERM AS
FAR AS GUN CONTROL IS CONCERNED.
THAT WILL BE A PRIORITY.
HE WANTS TO USE THE OFFICE OF
THE PRESIDENCY TO TRY TO SAVE
SOME LIVES, AND I THINK HE'S
GOING TO DO THE BEST HE CAN ON
THIS AREA.
I DON'T KNOW IF HE'LL SUCCEED,
BECAUSE THIS IS A TOUGH ISSUE,
AS YOU KNOW, IN THE U.S. SENATE,
U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,
BUT HE'LL GIVE IT A SHOT.
>> I THINK THAT'S RIGHT.
AND I THINK HE'S PICKED UP ON
WHAT'S A NATIONAL MOOD THAT I
DETECT AFTER THIS PARTICULAR
HORRIFYING INCIDENT, ONE OF THE
WORST YOU COULD POSSIBLY
IMAGINE.
I DETECT THERE'S A DIFFERENT
MOOD ABOUT THIS ISSUE AND ACTION
HAS TO BE TAKEN.
THE AMERICAN PUBLIC ARE GOING TO
DEMAND IT.
WOLF, FOR NOW, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH INDEED.
>>> THE TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN
RAISES DIFFICULT AND PAINFUL
QUESTIONS, QUESTIONS PEOPLE
ACROSS THE COUNTRY ARE ALL
WRESTLING WITH TONIGHT.
WHEN WE COME BACK, A CONSULTANT
ON MANY MASS SHOOTINGS.
WHAT HE NOW THINKS.
>>> WITH CANDLES, FLOWERS, AND
CARDS, PEOPLE GATHERED TONIGHT
AT A MEMORIAL FOR THE VICTIMS IN
NEWTOWN.
WE'RE LEARNING MORE DETAILINGS
ABOUT THE GUNMAN, ADAM LANZA.
JOINING ME IS AMADOR, HE'S
CONSULTED ON MANY MASS SHOOTINGS
IN THE PAST.
WE SPOKE ON FRIDAY.
RIGHT AT THE TOP, I WANT TO TALK
ABOUT SOMETHING WE DISCUSSED,
WHICH IS ABOUT THE POTENTIAL
MENTAL ILLNESS THAT THIS YOUNG
MAN SUFFERED FROM.
IT'S SUGGESTED THAT IT IS
POSSIBLY ASBERGERS, A FORM OF
AUTISM.
CLARIFY THAT AND CLARIFY WHETHER
THERE'S ANY REAL SCIENCE THAT
SUGGEST PEOPLE THAT HAVE THAT
KIND OF CONDITION MIGHT BE
VIOLENT.
>> THERE IS NONE.
THERE'S ABSOLUTELY NO EVIDENCE
THAT IF YOU HAVE ASBERGER'S,
YOU'RE MORE LIKELY TO BE VIOLENT
THAN ANYBODY ELSE.
I GOT SOME E-MAILS AND BLOGS
AFTER OUR LAST CONVERSATION.
I DIDN'T INTEND TO SAY PEOPLE
WITH ASBERGER'S LACK EMPATHY,
THEY LACK THE ABILITY TO JUDGE
SOCIAL CUES.
I LOOK AT YOU LIKE YOU'RE
LOOKING AT ME, IT MAY LOOK LIKE
I DON'T HAVE EMPATHY, I WANTED
TO CLARIFY THAT AS WELL.
>> MORE AND MORE DETAIL
EMERGING, NO SIGN OF MOTIVE.
KILLED HIS MOTHER, WENT TO THE
SCHOOL AND CLEARLY LOOKS LIKE HE
PLANNED IT QUITE CAREFULLY.
THE FBI SEIZED A COMPUTER.
ONE OF THE THINGS THEY KNOW IS
HE WAS PLAYING PRETTY VIOLENT
VIDEO GAMES, REENACTING BATTLE
SCENES WITH GRAPHIC CHARACTERS
AND SO ON.
I WAS DEBATING THIS ON TWITTER
TODAY, IF YOU'RE WATCHING AND
WANT TO GET INVOLVED IN ANY OF
THIS, TELL ME, MANY HAVE BEEN
STRONG ABOUT ALL THESE THINGS.
PEOPLE SAYING THERE'S NO LINK
BETWEEN ANY OF THIS AND ANYONE
WATCHING VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES,
BUT HERE'S MY QUESTION.
IN ALL YOUR EXPERIENCE, IF
SOMEBODY IS MENTALLY ILL,
MENTALLY UNSTABLE, VULNERABLE,
IF YOU LIKE, AND THEY ARE
WATCHING VERY VIOLENT VIDEO
GAMES A LOT, CAN IT STIMULATE
THEM, DOES IT DESENSITIZE THEM,
CAN IT BE PART OF THE
PROVOCATION, IF YOU LIKE, FOR
MAKING THEM GO AND DO AN
ATROCITY?
>> I DON'T THINK IT'S PART OF
THE PROVOCATION.
LET ME SAY SOMETHING.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT MENTAL
ILLNESS, DOESN'T MEAN YOU'RE
MENTALLY UNSTABLE.
THE MAJORITY OF PEOPLE IN
TREATMENT WITH SERIOUS MENTAL
ILLNESSES LIKES ABERGER'S,
SCHIZOPHRENIA, BIPOLAR, ARE
STABLE, LIVING PRODUCTIVE LIVES,
ARE WORKING.
LET'S BE REALLY CLEAR ABOUT
THAT.
WHAT HAPPENS, I LOOK AT THAT
RESEARCH FOR MANY, MANY YEARS.
THERE WAS AN ATTEMPT TO BAN --
>> THE HEADLINE IS THAT, YES,
WHEN YOU'RE ENGAGED IN, YOU
KNOW, VERY VIVID VIDEOS WHERE
YOU'RE SHOOTING PEOPLE, KILLING
PEOPLE, WHAT HAPPENS IS YOU'RE
DESENSITIZED TO WHAT IT MEANS TO
PULL A TRIGGER.
CERTAINLY, THE SCIENCE THERE IS
VERY GOOD, BUT A LOT OF THAT
RESEARCH IS FLAWED IN THAT
PEOPLE ARE SELECTED NOT -- YOU
CAN'T KNOW AHEAD OF TIME IF THE
PEOPLE WHO ARE DRAWN TO THESE
GAMES ARE ALREADY PEOPLE PRONE
TO VIOLENCE AND AGGRESSION,
REGARDLESS OF THE ISSUE OF
MENTAL ILLNESS.
>> PEOPLE WHO PLAY THESE GAMES
ARE PERFECTLY NORMAL, WHATEVER
NORMAL MEANS THESE DAYS, AND IT
HAS NO AFFECT ON THEM, I TOTALLY
ACCEPT THAT.
ANOTHER ARGUMENT THAT'S BEEN
RAISING, MORGAN FREEMAN, THE
ACTOR, BLAMED THE MEDIA FOR ALL
OF THIS, COPYCAT SYNDROME, THE
MEDIA, BY MAKING AS HE PUT IT
ALMOST LIKE GROTESQUE HEROS OF
THESE PEOPLE BY CONSTANTLY
NAMING THEM, SOMEHOW PROPAGATE
THIS ONGOING SITUATION WITH SO
MANY MASS SHOOTINGS.
DO YOU THINK HE'S RIGHT?
I MEAN, I DIDN'T AGREE WITH HIM
RULING OUT GUN CONTROL --
>> I DON'T THINK HE'S RIGHT.
>> IS HE RIGHT?
>> NO, HE'S NOT.
I'LL BLAME THE MEDIA FOR ONE
THING ONLY, WHICH IS
RETRAUMATIZING US.
DO YOU REMEMBER WITH 9/11 THERE
WAS A CALL FOR THE MEDIA TO STOP
SHOWING THE JETS FLYING INTO THE
BUILDINGS, BECAUSE PSYCHOLOGISTS
LIKE MYSELF AND OTHERS WERE
SEEING OUR PATIENTS HAVING VIVID
FLASHBACKS, NIGHTMARES,
POST-TRAUMATIC STRESS DISORDER
REACTION.
EXCESSIVE COVERAGE OF THIS CAN
BE TRAUMATIZING.
I'VE LOOKED AT PICTURES OF DEAD
CHILDREN AND BABIES IN THE CASES
I'VE WORKED ON AND HAD
NIGHTMARES.
ONE CASE IN PARTICULAR I STILL
HAVE FLASHBACKS TO JUST LOOKING
AT PICTURES, BUT NO, IT DOESN'T
CAUSE THIS KIND OF THING.
CAN I SAY ONE THING REALLY,
REALLY CLEARLY THAT I ONLY
TOUCHED ON ON FRIDAY, YOUR
CHANCES OF BEING SHOT AND KILLED
IN A MASS SHOOTING LIKE THIS ARE
ACTUALLY LESS THAN BEING STRUCK
BY LIGHTNING.
I'M NOT SAYING WE SHOULDN'T
COVER THIS AND TALK ABOUT THIS,
BUT, YOU KNOW, I'M SORRY, MORGAN
FREEMAN, THIS IS NOT CAUSING --
>> I'M HEARING APPARENTLY MORGAN
FREEMAN HAS COME OUT AND SAID
IT'S A HOAX, ALTHOUGH IT'S BEEN
RUNNING ALL OVER THE MEDIA FOR
THE LAST 24 HOURS.
IT MAY BE A HOAX, AS HE APPEARS
TO NOW BE CLARIFYING.
EITHER WAY, THOUGH, IT'S A
DEBATE A LOT OF PEOPLE I'VE BEEN
SEEING ON TWITTER, CNN ANCHORS,
ANDERSON COOPER AND OTHERS THINK
YOU SHOULDN'T BE NAMING.
IT'S SOMETHING PEOPLE SHOULD BE
THINKING ABOUT QUITE CAREFULLY.
>> IT IS A VALID THING TO BE
THINKING ABOUT, BUT THEN YOU
TURN TO THE RESEARCH, IF YOU
HAVE VIABLE RESEARCH TO LOOK AT,
YOU CAN LOOK AT EXPERTS WHO CAN
ASSESS THE TRUTHFULNESS OF THE
CONCLUSIONS.
WE DON'T SEE THAT COVERAGE LIKE
THIS CAUSES VIOLENCE.
>> FINAL QUESTION, EVERYBODY
WANTS TO KNOW THE SAME THING,
WHY WOULD A 20-YEAR-OLD BOY WHO
JUST SEEMED TO BE A LITTLE BIT
OF A LONER, LITTLE BIT STRANGE,
BUT NOTHING DANGEROUS AT ALL,
WHY WOULD HE GO TO A SCHOOL AND
KILL 20, 5, 6, 7-YEAR-OLD KIDS?
>> THE PERSON THAT HAS THE
ANSWER MAINLY IS ADAM.
ONE THING WE KNOW IS PEOPLE WITH
MENTAL ILLNESSES AND PEOPLE WHO
DON'T HAVE MENTAL ILLNESSES WHO
DO THESE THINGS ISOLATE
THEMSELVES FIRST.
WHAT WE NEED TO DO IS BUILD
BRIDGES TO THESE PEOPLE.
I TELL YOU WHAT, THE PEOPLE WHO
ARE VIOLENT AND ARE PRONE TO
SUICIDE, IN MY FIELD, WE PREVENT
THOSE KINDS OF THINGS ALL THE
TIME WHEN WE BUILD A
RELATIONSHIP WITH THE PERSON.
THEY WILL TALK TO ME, YOU KNOW
WHAT, DOC, I'M SO ANGRY I'M
THINKING ABOUT KILLING MY
MOTHER.
>> HIS COMPUTER HARD DRIVE THE
FBI HAVE.
>>> WHEN WE COME BACK, WHAT TO
DO ABOUT GUNS.
IT'S TRULY A QUESTION ABOUT LIFE
AND DEATH AND FEELINGS ON BOTH
SIDES ARE VERY MOTIVE.
I'LL TALK TO BOTH SIDES AFTER
THE BREAK.
>>> AND WE WILL HAVE TO CHANGE.
SINCE I'VE BEEN PRESIDENT, THIS
IS THE FOURTH TIME WE HAVE COME
TOGETHER TO COMFORT A GRIEVING
COMMUNITY TORN APART BY MASS
SHOOTINGS.
FOURTH TIME WE'VE HUGGED
SURVIVORS, THE FOURTH TIME WE'VE
CONSOLED THE FAMILIES OF
VICTIMS.
AND IN BETWEEN, THERE HAVE BEEN
AN ENDLESS SERIES OF DEADLY
SHOOTINGS ACROSS THE COUNTRY,
ALMOST DAILY REPORTS OF VICTIMS,
MANY OF THEM CHILDREN.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA IN TONIGHT'S
VIGIL CALLING FOR CHANGE, BUT
THE QUESTION REMAINS WHAT
AMERICA SHOULD DO ABOUT GUNS.
PRESIDENT OF THE BRADY CAMPAIGN
TO PREVENT GUN VIOLENCE AND THE
ATTORNEY FOR THE MICHIGAN
COALITION FOR RESPONSIBLE GUN
OWNERS.
I WANT YOUR REACTION, FIRST OF
ALL, DAN GROSS, WHAT DO YOU MAKE
OF HOW THE PRESIDENT SAID, AND
HOW SERIOUS DO YOU THINK HE IS
ABOUT ACTUALLY DOING SOMETHING
RATHER THAN JUST WORDS?
>> WE'RE INSPIRED.
I MEAN, WE'RE INSPIRED TO TAKE
HIM AT HIS WORD.
THE PRESIDENT, SINCE THIS HAS
HAPPENED, HAS CALLED FOR
MEANINGFUL ACTION.
HE'S SAYING ALL THE RIGHT
THINGS, AND HE'S TALKING ABOUT
ALL THE RIGHT THINGS.
IT'S UP TO US, THE AMERICAN
PUBLIC NOW, INCLUDING ALL THE
VICTIMS THAT HAVE BEEN IMPACTED
BY THESE TRAGEDIES, TO MAKE SURE
HE DOES TAKE THAT ACTION.
THOSE ARE THE DOTS THAT NEED TO
BE CONNECTED.
THIS IS THE TIME.
CHANGE HAS TO HAPPEN.
AND THIS REALLY IS A PIVOTAL
MOMENT IN THE HISTORY OF THIS
ISSUE, AND YOU CAN JUST SENSE IT
WATCHING THIS TONIGHT AND SEEING
HOW THAT COMMUNITY IS GRIEVING
AND KNOWING HOW OUR WHOLE NATION
IS GRIEVING.
WE DO THINK THIS IS A TIME FOR
CHANGE AND WE DO THINK PRESIDENT
OBAMA IS GOING TO LEAD US IN THE
RIGHT DIRECTION.
>> STEVE, THE NATURE OF THIS
DEBATE, I THINK, NEEDS TO BE
CRYSTALLIZED AND CLARIFIED.
TOO MANY PEOPLE ON EACH SIDES
TAKE POSITIONS AND PUT WORDS IN
THE MOUTH OF THEIR OPPONENTS.
YOU THE REALITY IS THIS, NOBODY