CONTROL DEBATE IS RAGING IN THE
AFTERMATH OF THE NEWTOWN SCHOOL
SHOOTING, AS THE WHITE HOUSE AND
NATIONAL POLLS SHOW A CHANGING
ATTITUDE.
WILL THIS TRAGEDY INSPIRE
WASHINGTON TO ACT?
>>> HERE IN NEWTON, STUDENTS
RETURNING BACK TO SCHOOL THIS
MORNING, BUT THEY WON'T BE GOING
BACK TO SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
AT LEAST NOT YET AS ANOTHER
LITTLE GIRL LAID TO REST, JUST
ONE DAY AFTER TWO FIRST GRADE
BOYS BURIED.
>>> A NEW SIGN THAT THE TIDE
COULD BE TURNING ON GUN CONTROL.
GUN CONTROL STOCKS UNDER FIRE.
A PENSION FUND MAY HAVE TO STRIP
INVESTMENTS.
>>> AND MOVEMENT ON THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
WE MAY BE MOVING MUCH CLOSER TO
A DEAL, WITH THE PRESIDENT
MAKING A SURPRISE OFFER.
>>> IT IS TUESDAY, DECEMBER
18th.
YOU'RE WATCHING A SPECIAL
EDITION OF "STARTING POINT" FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE BEGIN RIGHT NOW.
>>> WELCOME, EVERYBODY.
A SPECIAL EDITION OF "STARTING
POINT," LIVE THIS MORNING FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, THE SITE,
OF COURSE, WHERE AN UNTHINKABLE
MASSACRE AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
HAS REALLY SHIFTED THE LANDSCAPE
IN THE GUN CONTROL DEBATE.
HERE IS THE LATEST ON THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA MEETING WITH
SENIOR STAFF AND CABINET MEMBERS
YESTERDAY, TO SEE PROPOSALS THAT
WILL INCLUDE REINSTATING A BAN
ON AUTOMATIC WEAPONS.
OVERNIGHT, WE'VE LEARNED DICK'S
SPORTING GOODS HAS BANNED THE
SALE OF AR-15 RIFLES AND OTHER
GUNS LIKE IT.
IN FACT, THE MODERN SPORTING
RIFLES SECTION OF DICK'S
WEBSITE, BLANK THIS MORNING.
THE COMPANY RELEASED A STATEMENT
SAYING THIS.
OUT OF RESPECT FOR THE VICTIMS
AND THEIR FAMILIES, WE HAVE
REMOVED ALL GUNS IN OUR STORE
NEAREST NEWTOWN AND SUSPENDED
THE SALE OF MODERN SPORTING
RIFLES IN ALL OF OUR STORES
CHAIN WIDE.
IN THIS COMMUNITY, GRIEF
COUNSELORS AND EXTRA POLICE
PATROLS WILL BE ON HAND THIS
MORNING WHEN CHILDREN, ALL OVER
NEWTOWN HEAD BACK TO CLASS FOR
THE FIRST TIME SINCE FRIDAY.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IS
A CRIME SCENE AND IT REMAINS
CLOSED.
JESSICA REKOS, ONE OF 20
CHILDREN KILLED ON FRIDAY, WILL
BE LAID TO REST ON FRIDAY.
6 YEARS OLD.
ADORED HORSES.
COULDN'T WAIT FOR HER TENTH
BIRTHDAY.
HER PARENTS PROMISED HER, IN
FACT, WHEN SHE WAS 10, THEY
WOULD BUY A HORSE FOR HER.
AFTER NEWTOWN BURIED TWO
6-YEAR-OLD BOYS, NOAH POZNER WHO
LOVED TACOS, AND JACK PINTO WHO
LOVED THE NEW YORK GIANTS.
MORE THROUGHOUT THE MORNING,
INCLUDING GUN CONTROL LAWS.
FIRST, JOHN BERMAN WITH
DEVELOPING INFORMATION ON FISCAL
CLIFF NEGOTIATIONS.
>>> FISCAL CLIFF TALKS HAVEN'T
RECEIVED MUCH ATTENTION IN
RECENT DAYS FOR GOOD REASON.
BUT TODAY IS THE TWO-WEEK
WARNING, WITH SOME GOOD NEWS TO
REPORT.
OVERNIGHT, WE LEARNED PRESIDENT
OBAMA MADE AN EYE OPENING OFFER
IN TALKS WITH HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER.
UNDER THE NEW PROPOSALS, TAX
RATES WOULD GO UP ON THOSE
MAKING ABOVE $400,000.
A BIG SHIFT.
THE PRESIDENT HAS LONG
CAMPAIGNED ON THAT NUMBER,
STARTING AT $250,000.
THE PRESIDENT ALSO OFFERING
SPENDING CUTS WORTH $200
BILLION.
FOR HIS PART, SPEAKER BOEHNER
WHO HAS ALL ALONG REFUSED TO
CONSIDER ANY RAISING IN THE TAX
RATES HAS PROPOSED TAX RATES FOR
HOUSEHOLDS MAKING $1 MILLION.
SO MOVEMENT FROM BOTH SIDES.
CNN'S DAN LOTHIAN IN WASHINGTON
WITH THE LATEST ON THIS.
GOOD MORNING, DAN.
>> GOOD MORNING, JOHN.
THE BIG QUESTION, CAN SPEAKER
BOEHNER SELL THIS PROPOSAL TO
HOUSE REPUBLICANS?
THIS IS VERY DRAMATIC, PRESIDENT
OBAMA HAD ALWAYS DUG IN, SAYING
THERE WAS NO DEAL UNLESS TAXES
WENT UP ON HOUSEHOLDS MAKING
MORE THAN $250,000.
NOW THE PRESIDENT RAISING THAT
TO $400,000.
THIS NEW PROPOSAL OR
COUNTERPROPOSAL COMING DURING A
MEETING AT THE WHITE HOUSE
BETWEEN THE PRESIDENT AND
SPEAKER BOEHNER YESTERDAY.
IT LASTED 45 MINUTES.
IN ADDITION, THE PRESIDENT
PROPOSING $1.2 TRILLION IN NEW
REVENUE.
DOWN FROM 1$1.4 TRILLION AND 1$2
TRILLION IN SPENDING CUTS.
THIS MEETS THE DEMAND THAT
SPEAKER BOEHNER HAD FOR AN EQUAL
AMOUNT OF SPENDING CUTS TO
REVENUE.
BUT HOUSE REPUBLICAN AIDES SAY
WHILE THIS IS A STEP IN THE
RIGHT DIRECTION, THEY DON'T
BELIEVE THE PRESIDENT'S MATH
REALLY ADDS UP.
BRENDAN BUCK SAYS A PROPOSAL
THAT INCLUDES $1.3 TRILLION IN
REVENUE FOR ONLY $930 BILLION IN
SPENDING CUTS CANNOT BE
CONSIDERED BALANCED.
SO STILL SOME DISTANCE HERE
BETWEEN BOTH SIDES CAN ACTUALLY
REACH AN AGREEMENT HERE.
WHITE HOUSE SOURCES SAY THAT
THIS IS NOT THE FINAL OFFER FROM
THE PRESIDENT, SIGNALING THERE
COULD BE SOME ROOM FOR
COMPROMISE, JOHN.
>> A BIG DAY FOR SPEAKER BOEHNER
AS WELL.
10:00 EASTERN TIME, SCHEDULED TO
MEET WITH HOUSE REPUBLICAN
MEMBERS TO UPDATE THEM ON
NEGOTIATIONS.
REALLY NEEDS TO TAKE THEIR
TEMPERATURE ON THIS, DOESN'T HE?
>> HE DOES.
A LOT OF HOUSE REPUBLICANS HAVE
BEEN UNWILLING TO BUDGE ON
INCOMES, TAX HIKES GOING UP FOR
EVEN HIGH-INCOME AMERICANS, AND
NOW JOHN BOEHNER IS PROPOSAL
THAT $1 MILLION, THE PRESIDENT
NOW WITH $400,000.
AND SO THIS IS A TOUGH SELL FOR
HOUSE REPUBLICANS WHO HAVE
INSISTED THAT THEY WANTED THOSE
EXTENSIONS TO CONTINUE FOR ALL
AMERICANS, BECAUSE THEY BELIEVE
THAT IT WILL HAVE A NEGATIVE
DOWN TURN PRESSURE ON THE
ECONOMY.
THEY WILL PUT PRESSURE ON THOSE
WHO ARE THE JOB CREATORS.
A BIG SELL.
INTERESTING TO SEE IF THEY CAN
CONVINCE THOSE WHO ARE PUSHING
FORWARD.
>> WE'LL CHECK BACK IN WITH YOU
A LITTLE BIT.
DAN LOTHIAN, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
>>> BACK
TO NEWTOWN AND SOLEDAD.
>> WE MENTIONED THE GUN CONTROL
DEBATE HAS TAKEN ON NEW URGENCY
AFTER FRIDAY'S MASSACRE AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
MORE LAWMAKERS MOVING IN THE
DIRECTION OF TIGHTER GUN LAWS IN
THE AFTERMATH OF THE TRAGEDY.
EMILY SCHMIDT LIVE IN
WASHINGTON, D.C. WITH DETAILS.
EMILY.
>> SOLEDAD, GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
YESTERDAY IN THE SENATE, A
MOMENT OF SILENCE FOR THE
VICTIMS OF NEWTOWN, A TIME WHEN
WORDS WEREN'T NECESSARY.
ACROSS THE COUNTRY, OTHER
RESPONSES TO THE SHOOTING ARE
BEGINNING SPEAK FOR THEMSELVES.
ONE OF THEM COMING COMMERCIALLY.
TAKE A LOOK AT WHAT'S HAPPENING
AT DICK'S SPORTING GOODS.
A MAJOR RETAILER.
GO TO THEIR WEBSITE THIS MORNING
AND LOOK FOR MODERN SPORTING
RIFLES, THE WEBSITE WILL TURN UP
A BLANK PAGE.
THAT IS BECAUSE DICK'S SAID IT'S
SUSPENDING SALES OF THAT WEAPON
NATIONWIDE.
ALSO REMOVING ALL GUNS FROM ITS
STORE THAT IS CLOSEST TO
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
OUT OF RESPECT IT SAYS FOR THE
VICTIMS AND FAMILIES AFFECTED BY
THE NEWTOWN SHOOTINGS, UNCLEAR
HOW LONG THAT SUSPENSION WILL
LAST.
BUT CERTAINLY SOME LAWMAKERS IN
WASHINGTON ARE SAYING THEY WANT
TO SEE MORE PERMANENT CHANGES.
SENATOR DIANNE FEINSTEIN SAYS
THERE IS NO SECOND AMENDMENT
RIGHT TO BEAR EVERY TYPE OF
WEAPON POSSIBLE.
SHE WANTS TO SEE CHANGES.
>> I'M GOING TO DO AN ASSAULT
WEAPONS PIECE OF LEGISLATION AND
IT'S GOING TO BE STRONG, AND
IT'S GOING TO BE DEFINITIVE, AND
IT'S GOING TO BAN BY NAME AT
LEAST 100 MILITARY-STYLE
SEMIAUTOMATIC ASSAULT WEAPONS
AND IT WILL BAN BIG CLIPS,
DRUMS, OR STRIPS OF MORE THAN 10
BULLETS, AND IT'S THIS
PARTICULAR CATEGORY OF WEAPON
WHICH THE BUSHMASTER IS, IT'S A
KILLER WEAPON.
>> WHITE HOUSE SPOKESMAN JAY
CARNEY SAYS THE ASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN IS A COMPLEX ISSUE REQUIRING
SOME PLEX SOLUTIONS.
WE ARE HEARING FROM THE WHITE
HOUSE THAT THE PRESIDENT IS
PUTTING CABINET MEMBERS TO TASK
ON THAT.
BACK TO YOU.
>> HAVE YOU SOME POLLS YOU WANT
TO SHARE?
>> AN INSTANT SPIKE IN HOW
PEOPLE ARE REACTING TO THIS.
CBS NEWS ASKED DO YOU WANT MORE
STRICT OR LESS STRICT GUN
CONTROL RULES.
OVER THE WEEKEND THIS NUMBER
WENT UP 18%, SINCE THE QUESTION
WAS ASKED LAST ASKED IN APRIL.
ABC NEWS/WASHINGTON POST POLL
TAKEN OVER THE PAST FEW DAYS
SHOWS SUPPORT FOR THIS
LEGISLATION GOING UP.
LAWMAKERS WATCHING THIS, WAITING
TO SEE IF THIS IS A QUICK CHANGE
IN SENTIMENT OR A REAL SHIFT IN
POLICY DEBATE.
SOLEDAD.
>> ALL RIGHT, EMILY.
THANK YOU FOR THE UPDATE.
COMING UP, WE'LL TALK WITH WEST
VIRGINIA SENATOR JOE MANCHIN, A
MEMBER OF THE NRA, WHO SAYS
EVERYTHING SHOULD BE ON THE
TABLE WHEN IT COMES TO GUN LAWS,
ALL SCHOOLS IN NEWTOWN WILL
REOPEN TODAY, EXCEPT SANDY HOOK
HE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WHICH
REMAINS AN ACTIVE CRIME SCENE.
STUDENTS RETURNING AND FAMILIES,
TRYING TO GET BACK TO A
PRODUCTIVE ROUTINE.
OF COURSE, THE PAIN IS STILL,
STILL DEEP.
CNN'S SANDRA ENDOHAS OUR REPORT.
>> IN THE WAKE OF TRAGEDY, A
STEP TOWARD NORMAL SEE, FOR
NEWTOWN KIDS THAT MEANS GOING
BACK TO SCHOOL.
>> WE ALSO ARE GOING TO BE A
LITTLE BIT WORRIED, BECAUSE WE
KNOW WHAT WE THOUGHT WAS A
SECURE SCHOOL HAD THIS HAPPEN TO
THEM.
>> Reporter: BUT FACING FEAR MAY
BE THE FIRST STEP TO OVERCOME
THIS TRAGEDY.
>> CHILDREN HAVE TO GET BACK TO
SCHOOL.
IF WE LET THE SORT OF TERROR IN
OUR LIVES ANYWHERE IN THIS
COUNTRY, WE'VE LOST.
WE HAVE TO GET KIDS BACK TO
SCHOOL AGAIN.
>> CLASSES RESUMING FOR 5,400
STUDENTS IN THE DISTRICT, EXCEPT
FOR THOSE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
MONDAY, ALL SCHOOLS CLOSED AS
TEACHERS AND ADMINISTRATORS
TRAINED WITH EXPERTS ON HOW TO
HANDLE THE AFTERMATH.
MANY PARENTS WE SPOKE WITH
AGREE, KIDS BELONG BACK IN
SCHOOL.
>> I THINK ONE OF THE BIG THINGS
WE HAVE TO DO IS HAVE SOME SORT
OF NORMALCY.
AND SCHOOL IS PART OF THAT.
>> UNFORTUNATELY, YOU KNOW,
WE'RE LIVING IN THIS WORLD WHERE
SOMETIMES EVIL PREVAILS
SOMETIMES.
BUT WE JUST ARE BELIEVING THAT
GOOD WILL OVERCOME THIS.
>> SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY REMAINS
A CRIME SCENE.
FURNITURE AND SUPPLIES WERE
MOVED TO CHALK HILL MIDDLE
SCHOOL IN NEIGHBORING MONROE,
WHERE SANDY HOOK STUDENTS WILL
EVENTUALLY RESUME CLASSES.
>> WHEN CHILDREN COME IN,
WHENEVER SCHOOL IS STARTED, THEY
WALK INTO THE CLASSROOM IT, WILL
LOOK AS CLOSE AS POSSIBLE TO
THEIR CLASSROOM THAT THEY LEFT.
>> GRIEF COUNSELORS AND POLICE
OFFICERS WILL BE ON HAND AT
NEWTOWN SCHOOLS, AND PRINCIPALS
HAVE ASKED PARENTS TO TALK TO
THEIR CHILDREN ABOUT THE TRAGEDY
BEFORE THEY HEAD BACK INTO THE
CLASSROOMS.
TEACHERS AS WELL WILL TALK ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED HERE ON FRIDAY IN
AN AGE-APPROPRIATE MANNER.
SOLEDAD.
>> JUST A BRUTAL DAY FOR THEM
TODAY.
SANDRA ENDO, THANK YOU, SANDRA.
>>> DIFFERENT KIND OF FALLOUT TO
TELL YOU ABOUT IN THE WAKE OF
THE CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTING.
NEW DEVELOPMENTS OVERNIGHT IN
THE GUN INDUSTRY.
CHRISTINE ROMANS HAS DETAILS ON
THAT.
>> GOOD MORNING.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT THE COMPANY
THAT OWNS BUSHMASTER.
BUSHMASTER FIREARMS IS THE
COMPANY THAT MADE THE 223
CALIBER ASSAULT WEAPON THAT WAS
USED IN THE SHOOTING.
HERE IS HOW THE MONEY GOES.
CERBERUS, A BIG PRIVATE EQUITY
COMPANY.
BIG INVESTORS.
IT ACTUALLY PUT TOGETHER A GROUP
OF THESE FIREARMS COMPANIES INTO
SOMETHING CALLED FREEDOM GROUP,
AND ONE OF THE INVESTORS INTO
THIS IS THE CALIFORNIA STATE
TEACHERS RETIREMENT SYSTEM.
HAVE YOU TECHNICALLY AS INDIRECT
INVESTORS, CALIFORNIA TEACHERS
WHO OWN ABOUT 6% OF BUSHMASTER,
THE COMPANY THAT MADE THAT
FIREARM.
TODAY, CERBERUS, THE PRIVATE
EQUITY FIRM, SAYS IT'S LOOKING
TO SELL FREEDOM GROUP AND THE
MAKER OF BUSH MASTER AND GET OUT
OF THAT BUSINESS.
IN TERMS OF PRIVATE EQUITY, THAT
IS AN UNUSUAL TURN OF EVENTS, A
COMPANY WANTING TO GET OUT OF
BUSINESS.
CERBERUS SAYS IT'S APPARENT THAT
THE SANDY HOOK TRAGEDY IS A
WATERSHED EVENT THAT HAS RAISED
THE NATIONAL DEBATE ON GUN
CONTROL TO AN UNPRECEDENTED
LEVEL.
IT IS NOT OUR ROLE TO TAKE
POSITIONSOR ATTEMPT TO SHAPE OR
INFLUENCE THE GUN CONTROL POLICY
DEBATE, THERE ARE, HOWEVER,
ACTIONS THAT WE AS A FIRM CAN
TAKE."
THEY ARE TRYING TO SELL THE
COMPANY THAT MAKES THE
BUSHMASTER.
THE CALIFORNIA TEACHERS
RETIREMENT SYSTEM, THEIR
SPOKESMAN OUT THIS MORNING WITH
A STATEMENT.
THERE ARE A LOT OF PRODUCTS THAT
CAN BE USED RESPONSIBLY OR
IRRESPONSIBLY.
IN THIS CASE IT WAS USED
NOW THAT A TRAGIC EVENT LIKE
THIS HAS OCCURRED, IT'S
SOMETHING WE WILL DISCUSS GOING
FORWARD.
WHAT THEY WILL DISCUSS, WHETHER
IT'S APPROPRIATE FOR A TEACHERS
PENSION TO BE INVESTED IN A
COMPANY THAT MAKES SEMI
AUTOMATIC WEAPONS AND A PRODUCT
THAT WAS USED TO KILL TEACHERS
AND STUDENTS.
SOLEDAD.
>> YEAH, I SYMPATHY ANYBODY WHO
IS INVESTING MONEY ANYWHERE ONE
WOULD THINK WOULD WANT TO GO
BACK AND EXAMINE NOT JUST
WEAPONS AND NOT JUST THIS
PARTICULAR INCIDENT.
WHAT IS YOUR MONEY IN?
WHAT ARE YOU LITERALLY
SUPPORTING?
THAT'S A VERY GOOD QUESTION.
CHRISTINE ROMANS, THANKS,
CHRISTINE.
>>> KIDS IN NEWTOWN GO BACK TO
SCHOOL, HOW CAN PARENTS AND
TEACHERS HELP TEACHERS FEEL
SAFE?
AFTER SUCH A VIOLENT EPISODE.
STEVE PERRY, CAPITAL PREP
MAGNATE SCHOOL, WILL JOIN US UP
NEXT.
WE LEAVE YOU WITH A TRIBUTE TO
SOME OF THE VICTIMS OF SANDY
HOOK.
THE JUDGES AND CONTESTANTS OF
"THE VOICE."
♪
SNOOR SMOO
HE SAID NASAL CONGESTION.
YEAH...I HEARD HIM.
[ Female Announcer ] TYLENOL®
COLD MULTI-SYMPTOM NIGHTTIME
RELIEVES NASAL CONGESTION.
NYQUIL® COLD AND FLU DOESN'T.
.
>>> CHILDREN IN EVERY SCHOOL
HERE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
EXCEPT FOR SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, OF COURSE, WHICH IS
STILL AN ACTIVE CRIME SCENE, ALL
HEAD BACK TO SCHOOL TODAY.
ON A TWO-HOUR DELAY, WHICH WILL
GIVE THE TEACHERS A LITTLE EXTRA
TIME TO PREPARE FOR CLASSES AND
ON HAND AT EVERY SCHOOL WILL BE
GRIEF COUNSELORS, BECAUSE, OF
COURSE, IT IS A VERY DIFFERENT
WORLD FOR THESE CHILDREN HEADING
BACK TO THAN THE ONE THEY LEFT
LAST WEEK.
STEVE PERRY, PRINCIPAL AND
PRESIDENT OF CAPITAL PREP
MAGNATE SCHOOL IN HARTFORD,
CONNECTICUT.
ABOUT AN HOUR'S DRIVE FROM HERE.
IF YOU WERE AMONG THE PRINCIPALS
AND TEACHERS INSIDE THE
LOCATION, THE STUDENTS FROM
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY WOULD BE
ATTENDING WHAT WOULD YOU BE
TELLING THEM?
>> FIRST THING IS WHAT I WOULD
TELL MY OWN COLLEAGUES, WHEN
CHILDREN ASK QUESTIONS,
RECOGNIZE YOU NEED TO KEEP YOUR
TERMS BROAD.
WE DON'T UNDERSTAND WHAT
HAPPENED, AND THE BEST THING WE
CAN DO IS FOCUS ON THE BROAD,
ALMOST FANTASTICAL TERMS LIKE
BAD THINGS SOMETIMES HAPPEN TO
GOOD PEOPLE.
AND IN ADDITION TO THAT, THERE
ARE NOW 20 MORAINE GELS IN THE
SKY HERE TO SUPPORT YOU.
>> WHAT SHOULD THE TONE BE?
>> ALL POSITIVE.
ALL POSITIVE.
ARE YOU GOING TO BE SAFE.
YOU ARE SAFE IN SCHOOLS.
>> HAD HAS TO BE SO HARD IF YOU
ARE A PERSON THAT SURVIVED THAT
MASSACRE.
HOW DO YOU NOT AS A TEACHER LOOK
AT THE FACES OF STUDENTS WHEN
YOU ARE SUFFERING ON YOUR OWN?
HOW DO THEY DO IT?
>> ONE OF THE FIRST THINGS I
SAID TO MY COLLEAGUES YESTERDAY
IS I WANT TO KNOW IF YOU'RE
OKAY.
BECAUSE BEFORE WE LEAVE THIS
ROOM, BEFORE WE BREAK THIS
HUDDLE AND GO OUT TO TAKE CARE
OF THE CHILDREN, I NEED TO KNOW
EVERYBODY HERE IS OKAY, IF YOU
ARE NOT, TAP OUT, LET SOMEBODY
HELP YOU FIRST, BECAUSE THE
TEACHERS HAVE TO FEEL GOOD
BEFORE THEY CAN GO IN AND MAKE
THE CHILDREN FEEL GOOD.
A HARD SELL TODAY.
IT WILL BE A HARD SELL FOR A
LONG TIME.
>> SHOULD THERE BE MOMENTS -- IN
MY KIDS SCHOOL, WE DON'T LIVE
VERY CLOSE TO HERE, THEY HAD
MEETINGS, AND TALKED WI ABOUT T.
SHOULD THEY PLOW ON AND DO MATH
AND SPELLING?
>> I DON'T THINK IT'S EITHER-OR.
YOU DO A COUPLE MINUTES TO PULL
TOGETHER SOME KIDS AND HAVE SOME
CONVERSATIONS, AND LISTEN --
LISTEN TO THE FLOW OF THE KIDS
TO BE HONESTLY WITH YOU,
SOLEDAD, A LOT OF KIDS HAVE
FATIGUE OVER THIS.
IT'S FREAKING THEM OUT.
THEY CAN'T SLEEP.
THEY WOULD LIKE TO PUMP THE
BRAKES AND TALK ABOUT SOMETHING
DIFFERENT.
THEY WANT TO TALK ABOUT BALLET
REHEARSAL OR THE PLAY THEY HAVE
COMING UP OR THE BASKETBALL
GAME.
THEY WANT TO TALK ABOUT
SOMETHING DIFFERENT THIS IS A
BIT MUCH FOR THEM.
>> A LOT OF CONVERSATION HAS
MOVED TO GUN CONTROL DEBATE AND
THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO SUGGEST
THAT WHAT COULD BE HELPFUL WOULD
BE WEAPONS INSIDE OF SCHOOLS.
>> ABSOLUTELY ABSURD.
SUITLY ABSURD.
>> THERE ARE SCHOOLS WITH ARMED
GUARDS IN THEM.
>> THERE ARE SCHOOLS THAT HAVE
POLICE SUBSTATIONS IN THEM.
BUT THAT WOULDN'T HAVE SAVED
THESE CHILDREN.
THE PROBLEM HERE IS THAT THAT
INDIVIDUAL WHO WAS CLEARLY
DERANGED, HAD GUNS.
IT'S NOT THAT SOMEBODY ELSE ON
THE INSIDE WOULD HAVE HAD GUNS.
YOU COULD HAVE HAD NAVY
S.E.A.L.S AT THE FRONT DOOR WITH
ARMS DRAWN TO STOP HIM.
THAT WOULD BE THE ONLY WAY.
HE CAME IN WITH FOUR WEAPONS,
SHOT HIS WAY INTO THE SCHOOL.
NOT MUCH YOU CAN DO ABOUT THAT.
IT WAS A SECURE SCHOOL.
AND THAT WAS THE TRUTH.
HE COULD HAVE GOTTEN INTO ANY
BUILDING IN THE UNITED STATES
WITH THAT LEVEL OF WEAPONS.
>> SHEHERE IS WHAT GOVERNOR RIC
PERRY SAID.
>> IN THE STATE OF TEXAS WITH
OUR CONCEALED WEAPONS LAWS.
IF YOU GO THROUGH THE PROCESS
AND DUALLY BA L LY BACKGROUNDED
TRAINED, YOU SHOULD BE ABLE TO
CARRY YOUR HANDGUN ANYWHERE IN
THIS STATE.
>> WHY ARE YOU SHAKING YOUR
HEAD, NO, NO, NO?
>> WITH ALL DUE RESPECT TO
GOVERNOR PERRY, HE HAS TO THINK
BEYOND THE SMALL MINDEDNESS, I
WANT TO CARRY A GUN FOR GUN'S
SAKE.
TOO MANY PEOPLE HAVE DIED.
OUR CHILDREN ARE FRIGHTENED TO
GO BACK TO SCHOOL BECAUSE WE
HAVE LAWLESSNESS, A FEEL IN OUR
COUNTRY.
SO MANY PEOPLE ARE AFRAID THAT
SOMEBODY IS CARRYING A GUN.
STEP BACK FOR A SECOND.
TAKE A LOOK AT THE REST OF THE
COUNTRY AND REALIZE THAT NOT
EVERYBODY THINKS CARRYING A GUN
IS COOL.
SOME PEOPLE ARE AFRAID OF IT.
THERE ARE PEOPLE IN THE COUNTRY
THAT ARE FEARFUL IN THEIR OWN
NEIGHBORHOOD BECAUSE OF GUNS.
THEY DON'T MAKE EVERYONE FEEL
SAFER.
IN MANY CASES THEY MAKE CHILDREN
FEEL UNSAFE.
AND THAT'S THE PROBLEM.
>> DR. STEVE PERRY.
ALWAYS NICE TO HAVE YOU WITH US.
APPRECIATE IT.
>>> COMING UP, WE'LL TALK WITH
JOE MANCHIN.
TALKED ABOUT PROTECTING THE
SECOND AMENDMENT AND USES A LOT
OF GUNS IN HIS ADVERTISEMENT FOR
CAMPAIGNS, BUT NOW TALKING ABOUT
CHANGING THE COUNTRY'S GUN LAWS.
>>> A DRAMATIC RESCUE.
A REPORTER FREED FROM CAPTORS IN
SYRIA TODAY.
WE'LL UPDATE YOU ON WHAT
HAPPENED THERE.
LIVE REPORTS, UP NEXT.
♪
[ Gordon ] FOR SOME
THIS LINE IS A CONVENIENCE.
HOW YOU DOING TODAY?
I'M GOOD THANKS.
HOW ARE YOU?
I'M GOOD.
[ Gordon ] BUT FOR OTHERS,
IT'S ALL THEY CAN AFFORD.
EVERY DAY NEARLY NINE MILLION
OLDER AMERICANS
DON'T HAVE ENOUGH TO EAT.
ANYTHING ELSE?
NO, NOT TODAY.
JOIN ME, AARP,
AND AARP FOUNDATION
IN THE DRIVE TO END HUNGER
BY VISITING
DRIVETOENDHUNGER.ORG.
IN THE DRIVE TO END HUNGER
ALRIWOAH! DID YOU GET THAT?
AND...FLIP!
YEP, LOOK AT THIS. IT TAKES
LIKE 20 PICTURES AT A TIME. I
NEVER MISS ANYTHING.
ISN'T THAT AWESOME?
UH THAT'S REALLY COOL.
YOU SHOULD UPLOAD THESE.
I KNOW, RIGHT?
THAT IS REALLY AMAZING.
THE PICTURES ARE SO CLEAR.
KEVIN'S A HANDSOME DEVIL
THAT PHONE DOES EVERYTHING!
SEARCH DOG TRICKS.
OKAY, SEE IF WE CAN TEACH
HIM SOMETHING COOL.
LOOK AT HOW LAZY KEVIN IS.
KEVIN, GET IT TOGETHER DUDE
CMON, KEVIN
TAKE 20 PICTURES WITH BURST
SHOT ON THE GALAXY S3.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYONE.
A HARROWING TALE, A REPORTER AND
HIS CREW HELD FOR FIVE DAYS IN
SYRIA, NOW FREE UNHARMED.
NBC SAYS RICHARD ENGEL AND HIS
CREW, SAFE AND OUT OF THE
COUNTRY.
NICK PATON WALSH FOLLOWING THIS
STORY.
A DRAMATIC SERIES OF EVENT.
>> ENGEL'S CREW CROSSED INTO
SYRIA ON THURSDAY.
NOTHING WAS HEARD.
NO RANSOM REQUEST, NO CONTACT.
UNTIL THEY APPEARED TO BE FREE
ON MONDAY.
SUBSEQUENTLY EMERGES, THEY WERE
PICKED UP, MR. ENGEL SAYS, BY A
MEN IN SKI MASKS.
15 OF THEM, WHO LEAPT OUT OF THE
BUSHES AND TOOK HIS TEAM AS
HOSTAGES.
THEY WERE MOVED AROUND THE
COUNTRY IN THE BACK OF AN OPEN
PICKUP, BLIND FOLDED AND BOUND,
BUT OTHERWISE NOT HARMED.
THEY WERE TRANSFERRED TO ANOTHER
LOCATION.
THIS ALL HAPPENING IN THE NORTH
OF SYRIA.
NOW, DURING THAT JOURNEY, THEY
SEEM TO HAVE COME ACROSS A GROUP
OF REBELS CALLED THE ATAR AL
SHAM BRIGADE, WHO ENTERED INTO A
GUN FIGHT WITH THEIR CAPTORS.
IT CAUSED THE NBC TEAM TO BE
FREE.
>> NO PHYSICAL HARM.
BUT PSYCHOLOGICAL FARM.
FA
HARM.
FAKE EXECUTIONS, ASKING THEM
WHICH ONE OF THEM THEY WOULD
LIKE TO BE EXECUTED FIRST.
>> THEY BELIEVE THAT THERE WAS A
REB
REGIME TO THE LOYALTY.
MR. ENGEL HAS GONE ON TO SAY
THAT THEY MAY HAVE BEEN THUGS.
IN CONTEXT TO THE CIVIL WAR IT
REFERS TO MILITIA LOYAL TOWARD
THE GOVERNMENT.
HE THINKS THEY MAY HAVE BEEN
HELD IN A BID TO TRY AND
EXCHANGE THEM FOR CAPTIVES HELD
BY THE REBELS, POTENTIALLY
IRANIAN AGENTS WORKING FOR THE
SYRIAN REGIME.
A COMPLEX SITUATION WHICH SEEMS
TO HAVE BEEN REMARKABLY RESOLVED
IN POSITIVE FASHION, OF COURSE,
SHOWS YOU HOW ANARCHY THINGS ARE
GETTING IN SYRIA.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
YOU AND I HAVE KNOWN RICHARD AND
HIS CAMERAMAN FOR A LONG TIME.
WE ARE ALL RELIEVED THIS
MORNING.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>>> LET'S GO BACK TO NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WHERE SOLEDAD IS.
>> ALL RIGHT.
JOHN, THANK YOU.
AND, YEAH, WE'RE ALL CONCERNED
ABOUT THE NEWS OF RICHARD ENGEL.
SUCH GOOD NEWS FOR EVERYONE.
>>> LET'S TALK MORE ABOUT WHAT'S
HAPPENING AMONG GUN SELLERS,
SOME TAKING ACTION AFTER THE
NEWTOWN SHOOTING.
WHAT DICK'S SPORTING GOOD IS
DOING.
IT WILL SURPRISE A LOT OF
PEOPLE.
NOT DONE BEFORE.
AND FAMOUSLY PRO GUN DEMOCRAT.
BUT SENATOR JOE MANCHIN HAVING A
CHANGE OF HEART?
HIS LATEST COMMENTS ON GUN
LEGISLATION WHEN WE COME BACK IN
A MOMENT.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
WHO HAVE USED AndroGel 1%,
THERE'S BIG NEWS.
PRESENTING AndroGel 1.62%.
BOTH ARE USED TO TREAT MEN
WITH LOW TESTOSTERONE.
AndroGel 1.62%
IS FROM THE MAKERS
OF THE NUMBER ONE PRESCRIBED
TESTOSTERONE
REPLACEMENT THERAPY.
IT RAISES YOUR TESTOSTERONE
LEVELS, AND...
IS CONCENTRATED,
SO YOU COULD USE LESS GEL.
AND WITH AndroGel 1.62%,
YOU CAN SAVE
ON YOUR MONTHLY PRESCRIPTION.
[ Male Announcer ]
DOSING AND APPLICATION SITES
BETWEEN THESE PRODUCTS DIFFER.
WOMEN AND CHILDREN SHOULD AVOID
CONTACT WITH APPLICATION SITES.
DISCONTINUE AndroGel
AND CALL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU SEE UNEXPECTED SIGNS
OF EARLY PUBERTY IN A CHILD,
OR, SIGNS IN A WOMAN
WHICH MAY INCLUDE
CHANGES IN BODY HAIR
OR A LARGE INCREASE IN ACNE,
POSSIBLY DUE TO
ACCIDENTAL EXPOSURE.
MEN WITH BREAST CANCER
OR WHO HAVE OR MIGHT HAVE
PROSTATE CANCER,
AND WOMEN WHO ARE,
OR MAY BECOME PREGNANT
OR ARE BREAST FEEDING
SHOULD NOT USE AndroGel.
SERIOUS SIDE EFFECTS
INCLUDE WORSENING
OF AN ENLARGED PROSTATE,
POSSIBLE INCREASED RISK
OF PROSTATE CANCER,
LOWER SPERM COUNT,
SWELLING OF ANKLES, FEET,
OR BODY,
ENLARGED OR PAINFUL BREASTS,
PROBLEMS BREATHING
DURING SLEEP,
AND BLOOD CLOTS IN THE LEGS.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT YOUR MEDICAL CONDITIONS
AND MEDICATIONS,
ESPECIALLY INSULIN,
CORTICOSTEROIDS, OR MEDICINES
TO DECREASE BLOOD CLOTTING.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR TODAY
ABOUT AndroGel 1.62%
SO YOU CAN USE LESS GEL.
LOG ON NOW
TO AndroGelOffer.com
AND YOU COULD PAY AS LITTLE
AS TEN DOLLARS A MONTH
FOR AndroGel 1.62%.
WHAT ARE YOU WAITING FOR?
THIS IS BIG NEWS.
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
>>> WELCOME BACK.
YOU'RE WATCHING "STARTING
POINT."
SPECIAL EDITION FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THE TRAGEDY HERE ON FRIDAY HAS
TRULY CHANGED THE CONVERSATION
ON GUN CONTROL IN THIS COUNTRY.
PRESIDENT OBAMA MET WITH MEMBERS
OF HIS CABINET YESTERDAY.
ORDERING IDEAS THAT WOULD
INCLUDE A BAN ON ASSAULT
WEAPONS.
AND THERE IS WORD OF A MAJOR
MOVE OVERNIGHT BY DICK'S
SPORTING GOODS.
451 STORES ACROSS 42 STATES.
OUT OF RESPECT TO THE VICTIMS IT
HAS PULLED ITS GUNS FROM THE
STORE CLOSE TOAST NST TO NEWTOW
SUSPENDED THE SALE OF AR-15sAND
GUNS LIKE IT ACROSS THE ENTIRE
CHAIN.
>>> IN THIS MORNING, CHILDREN IN
NEWTOWN WILL HEAD BACK TO SCHOOL
FOR THE FIRST TIME SINCE
FRIDAY'S SHOOTING.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY WILL
REMAIN CLOSED, IT'S AN ACTIVE
CRIME SCENE.
JESSICA REKOS WILL BE LAID TO
REST TODAY.
6 YEARS OLD.
COULDN'T WAIT FOR HER 10th
BIRTHDAY, BECAUSE HER PARENTS
SAID THEY WOULD BUY A HORSE FOR
HER.
DAN MALLOY CALLING FOR A MOMENT
OF SILENCE ONE WEEK AFTER THE
SHOOTING AT SANDY HOOK.
THE GOVERNOR CHOKING UP AS HE
TOLD WHY HE TOOK IT UPON HIMSELF
TO TELL THE FAMILIES WAITING ON
FRIDAY MORNING THAT THEIR LOVED
ONES WEREN'T GOING TO COME HOME.
>> IT WAS EVIDENT TO ME THAT
THERE WAS A RELUCTANCE TO TELL
PARENTS AND LOVED ONES THAT THE
PERSON THAT THEY WERE WAITING
FOR WAS NOT GOING TO RETURN.
I MADE THE DECISION THAT TO HAVE
THAT GO ON ANY LONG ER WAS WRON.
>> 6-YEAR-OLD NOAH POZNER LAID
TO REST YESTERDAY.
THAT'S A PICTURE OF HIM THERE.
HIS MOTHER'S NAME VERANIQUE
POSNER.
SHE READ A MOVING EULOGY TO HER
SON.
IT STARTS LIKE THIS "THE SKY IS
CRYING, AND THE FLAGS ARE AT
HALF MAST.
IT'S A SAD, SAD DAY.
BUT IT'S ALSO YOUR DAY, NOTICE
WRA, MY LITTLE MAN.
I HAD MISS YOUR FORCEFUL AND
PURPOSEFUL LITTLE STEPS STOMPING
THROUGH OUR HOUSE, THE PERPETUAL
SMILE, THE TWINKLE IN YOUR DARK
BLUE EYES FRAMED BY EYELASHES
THAT WOULD BE THE ENVY OF ANY
LADY IN THIS ROOM.
SHE GOES ON AND ENDS BY SAYING
THIS, I HAD JOIN YOU SOME DAY,
NOT TODAY, I STILL HAVE LOTS OF
MOMMY LOVE TO GIVE TO DANIELLE,
MICHAEL, SOPHIA, AND ARIELLE.
UNTIL THEN, YOUR MELODY WILL
LINGER IN OUR HEARTS FOREVER,
MAMA LOVES YOU, LITTLE MAN.
THE ENTIRE EULOGY, SO POWERFUL
AND BEAUTIFUL, ACAN BE SEEN IN
"THE NEW YORK TIMES," THEY HAVE
REPRINTED IT THERE.
AS WE TALKED ABOUT THE TRAGEDY
BRINGING GUN CONTROL LAWS TO THE
FOREFRONT, WE WANT TO BRING IN
JOE MANCHIN, CONSERVATIVE
DEMOCRAT FROM THE STATE OF
VIRGINIA, AND FAMOUSLY PRO GUN.
NICE TO HAVE YOU WITH US, SIR.
WE CERTAINLY APPRECIATE IT.
YOU HAVE SAID IT'S NOW TIME TO
TALK ABOUT GUN CONTROL.
WHAT DO YOU SPECIFICALLY MEAN?
>> SOLEDAD, WHAT WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT, I KNOW THAT EVERYBODY IS
GRIEVING AS HARD AS WE'RE
GRIEVING IN WEST VIRGINIA, AND I
CAN ONLY IMAGINE THE PAIN.
I JUST CAN, AS A PARENT AND
GRANDPARENT.
SO OUR HEARTS AND PRAYERS ARE
WITH ALL OF THE FAMILIES AND ALL
OF THE PEOPLE OF CONNECTICUT.
NEWTOWN.
I JUST -- I DON'T HAVE WORDS FOR
THAT.
AND MY SYMPATHIES FOR THEM WITH
THAT BEING SAID, WE HAVEN'T
HOPEFULLY BECOME A SOCIETY OR
BECOME EVEN A GOVERNING BODY
THAT WE CAN'T SIT DOWN AND TALK.
WE CAN'T LAY EVERYTHING ON THE
TABLE TO FIND OUT HOW DO WE MOVE
FORWARD?
WE HAVE CHALLENGES.
I'M A BIG PROPONENT OF COLIN
POWELL'S FIVE PROMISES TO
CHILDREN.
SECOND PROMISE, EVERY CHILD
SHOULD HAVE A SAFE PLACE IN
THEIR LIFE.
SOMETIMES IT'S NOT ALWAYS THE
HOME.
MORE THAN OFTEN, IT'S THE SCHOOL
AND IT LOOKS LIKE EVEN THAT HAS
BEEN TAKEN AWAY.
IT IS TIME TO SIT DOWN, TIME TO
LOOK AT A RESPONSIBLE,
REASONABLE APPROACH.
MENTAL ILLNESS, A CULTURE OF
VIOLENCE, SOMETIMES ACCEPTED,
EVEN GLORIFIED AND CERTAIN
MILITARY STYLE WEAPONS THAT AS A
HUNTER MYSELF, AS A PROUD
DEFENDER OF THE SECOND
AMENDMENT, AS A PROUD MEMBER OF
THE NRA, WE SHOULD QUESTION.
AND LOOK AND SEE IF THERE IS A
BETTER WAY TO DO THIS.
>> WOULD YOU THEN SUPPORT
LEGISLATION THAT WOULD BAN
ASSAULT WEAPONS.
WOULD YOU SUPPORT LEGISLATION
THAT WOULD GET RID OF HIGH
CAPACITY MAGAZINES?
>> SOLEDAD, THAT ALL HAS TO COME
TO THE TABLE.
IF IT'S A RESPONSIBLE,
REASONABLE MANNER, I THINK THAT
THE MAJORITY OF AMERICANS WOULD
SUPPORT A REASONABLE APPROACH TO
THAT.
I HAVE BEEN HUNTING ALL MY LIFE.
I HAVE EVER HAD MULTIPLE ROUNDS
OF CLIPS OF TEN OR MORE.
NOT NEEDED.
I NEVER GONE WITH A MILITARY
STYLE ASSAULT RIFLE HUNTING.
IT'S NOT NEEDED.
SO WE NEED TO QUESTION THAT.
WE NEED TO BRING THE NRA IN.
THESE ARE ALL GOOD PEOPLE.
THEY HAVE CHILDREN AND
GRANDCHILDREN, THEY ARE HURTING
TOO.
THEY ARE GRIEVING.
SO WE CAN'T VILLAINIZE, AND IF
YOU START VILLAINIZE, YOU WILL
PUSH THEM AWAY AND WE WON'T MOVE
FORWARD.
WHAT WILL HAPPEN IS A STALEMATE
AGAIN AND THAT'S NOT WHAT WE
DESIRE.
>> DO YOU WORRY ABOUT POLITICAL
BACKLASH?
YOU SAID YOU'RE A PROUD MEMBER
OF THE NRA, AND AS YOU KNOW,
THEY OFTEN FUND CANDIDATES
WHO -- AND WORK TO OVERTHROW
FRANKLY CANDIDATES WHO DON'T
SUPPORT THE SAME KINDS OF
BELIEFS AND LEGISLATION THAT
THEY SUPPORT.
DO YOU WORRY ABOUT BACKLASH FROM
CONSTITUENTS?
>> I COME FROM THE BEAUTIFUL,
GREAT STATE OF WEST VIRGINIA,
THE MOST WONDERFUL PEOPLE AND WE
SIT DOWN AND WORK THROUGH OUR
PROBLEMS, WE HAVE CHALLENGES, WE
SIT DOWN.
COME TO A CONCLUSION WITH THE
FACTS AND THAT'S WHAT WE'RE
ASKING FOR.
THERE IS ALWAYS GOING TO BE I
GUESS MOVEMENT OR POLITICAL
BACKLASH ON ANYTHING AND
EVERYTHING.
THE EASIEST VOTE TO TAKE IN
WASHINGTON IS A NO VOTE.
VOTE FOR NOTHING.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO EXPLAIN.
BUT IF YOU ARE WILLING TO MOVE
FORWARD AND FOR THE SAKE OF OUR
CHILDREN, SOLEDAD, WE HAD 20
BEAUTIFUL BABIES SLAUGHTERED.
THAT CANNOT BE TOLERATED IN
AMERICA.
SO DOES THAT BRING US TO THE
TABLE?
HAVE WE HAD SUCH A TOXIC
ATMOSPHERE, POLITICAL TOXIC
ATMOSPHERE WE CAN'T SET AND HAVE
A MATURE, INTELLIGENT DECISION
AND LOOK AT THINGS AND MAKE SURE
WE CAN PROTECT THE SECOND
AMENDMENT TO THE CONSTITUTION,
WHICH I WILL AS FERVENTLY AS
EVER.
I'M A PROUD MEMBER AND WILL
ALWAYS BE.
BUT WITH THAT, I'M A RESPONSIBLE
PARENT AND GRANDPARENT.
WE NEED TO LOOK.
HOW DO WE HANDLE MENTAL ILLNESS?
THIS ALL KNEES TO BE TALKED
ABOUT, IN A CULTURE OF VIOLENCE.
HOW HAVE WE GOTTEN WHERE WE ARE
TODAY?
WHEN YOU SAY THE BACKLASH, IT'S
A SHAME IN WASHINGTON, I HAVE
BEEN HERE TWO YEARS AS A U.S.
SENATOR.
I HAVE SEEN ALMOST A GUILT BY
ASSOCIATION.
PEOPLE AFRAID TO TALK TO OTHER
PEOPLE TO GET A TRULY
CONSTRUCTIVE DIALOG BECAUSE THEY
WERE AFRAID THEY WOULD BE
TAINTED OR TARGETED.
NOW IT'S ALMOST TO THE POINT
THAT WE'RE AFRAID TO HAVE AN
ADULT CONVERSATION.
SO GUILT BY CONVERSATION.
HAS IT GOTTEN TO THAT IN
WASHINGTON?
I HOPE NOT.
>> GOVERNOR PERRY SAID THIS
ABOUT WEAPONS.
I WANT TO PLAY A LITTLE BIT FOR
YOU.
>> IN THE STATE OF TEXAS, WITH
OUR CONCEALED HANDGUN LICENSE IF
YOU GO THROUGH THE PROCESS AND
YOU HAVE BEEN DULLY BACKGROUNDED
AND TRAINED AND YOU ARE A
CONCEALED HANDGUN LICENSED
CARRYING INDIVIDUAL, YOU SHOULD
BE ABLE TO CARRY YOUR HANDGUN
ANYWHERE IN THIS STATE.
>> DO YOU AGREE WITH THAT?
HE IS TALKING ABOUT TEXAS, HIS
STATE.
DO YOU THINK WE SHOULD BE ABLE
TO CARRY A GUN ANYWHERE?
>> SOLEDAD, HE'S TALKING ABOUT
THE LAWS WE HAVE IN THIS
COUNTRY.
THE LEGAL, LAW-ABIDING CITIZENS.
YOU KNOW, WE'RE NOT TALKING
ABOUT THAT.
WE'RE TALKING CAN WE GET RICK
PERRY TO SIT DOWN, A PROUD
MEMBER OF THE NRA, CAN WE GET
PEOPLE TO SIT DOWN AND HAVE AN
ADULT CONVERSATION?
THAT'S WHAT THIS REALLY IS
ABOUT.
IF WE CAN'T EVEN GET THEM TO THE
TABLE, DO YOU REALLY THINK WE'LL
HAVE SUCCESS IN BASICALLY HOW WE
KEEP OUR CHILDREN SAFER?
CHANGING THE VIOLENT CULTURE.
>> LET ME ASK YOU THIS --
>> I'M SORRY.
>> WHEN YOU LOOK AT ASSAULT-TYPE
WEAPONS, ESTIMATED TO BE
SOMEWHERE BETWEEN 2% TO 8%, SOME
OF THE NUMBERS I'VE SEEN,
INVOLVED IN GUN VIOLENCE.
SO THAT LEAVES YOU, I THINK IT'S
80% IS HANDGUNS INVOLVED IN GUN
VIOLENCE.
DOES THIS OPEN UP A CONVERSATION
TO --
>> I THINK WHAT YOU WILL SEE
HOPEFULLY -- SOLEDAD, HOPEFULLY
YOU WILL HAVE PROUD MEMBERS OF
THE NRA AND DEFENDERS OF THE
SECOND AMENDMENT WHO SAYS IT'S
TIME TO HAVE AN INTELLIGENT
CONVERSATION.
THE MILITARY ASSAULT RIFLES, IS
THAT SOMETHING NEEDED IN OUR
SOCIETY?
IT WAS DESIGNED FOR THE PURPOSE
OF OUR MILITARY AND OUR FIRST
RESPONDERS AND POLICE DEFENDING
US AS A NATION.
AND THOSE WHO ARE THE
DISCUSSIONS WE SHOULD BE HAVING,
ALONG WITH THE OTHER THINGS
WE'VE BEEN TALKING.
THE MENTAL HEALTH AND VIOLENT
CULTURE.
WE'RE HAVING A HARD TIME GETTING
PEOPLE OF DIFFERENT
PHILOSOPHICAL BELIEFS TO COME
OUT AND SIT DOWN.
THEY ARE AFRAID TO SPEAK OUT,
THINKING THAT ONE SIDE OR THE
OTHER MIGHT ATTACK THEM.
IT MIGHT BE POLITICALLY NOT
POPULAR.
AGAIN, I REMIND YOU, WE'RE
TALKING ABOUT CHILDREN HERE.
NEVER IN MY LIFE DID I EVER
THINK THAT I WOULD EVER SEE,
SOLEDAD, CHILDREN SLAUGHTERED IN
AMERICA.
I NEVER -- I CAN'T COMPREHEND
IT.
I WAS WITH MY GRANDCHILDREN THIS
PAST WEEKEND, I JUST CAN'T
COMPREHEND IT.
MY HEART GOES OUT.
I'M HURTING, I THINK ALL AMERICA
IS HURTING RIGHT NOW.
>> SENATOR JOE MANCHIN, THANK
YOU FOR BEING WITH US.
WE APPRECIATE IT.
>> THANK YOU.
>> JOHN BERMAN HAS A LOOK AT
OTHER STORIES MAKING NEWS THIS
MORNING.
>> 18-YEAR-OLD SERGIO CABATA IN
CUSTODY, ACCUSED OF THREATENING
A NEWTOWN STYLE MASSACRE.
HIS FACEBOOK POSTS SUGGESTED HE
WAS CONSIDERING A COPYCAT
RAMPAGE.
>>> A REPORT BY AN INDEPENDENT
PANEL THAT LOOKS AT THE DEADLY
ATTACK ON THE CONSULATE IN
BENGHAZI LIBYA.
THE REPORT ORDERED BY SECRETARY
OF STATE HILLARY CLINTON,
ALTHOUGH SHE WON'T TESTIFY SINCE
SHE'S RECOVERING FROM A
CONCUSSION.
THE ATTACK IN SEPTEMBER, YOU
KILLED FOUR AMERICANS, INCLUDING
CHRIS STEVENS, THE AMBASSADOR TO
LIBYA.
>>> A GIANT OF THE U.S. SENATE
HAS DIED.
SENATOR DANIEL INOUYE
REPRESENTED HAWAII FROM THE DAY
IT BECAME A STATE IN 1959.
HE WAS 88.
SUFFERED FROM RESPIRATORY
PROBLEMS.
SHAKEN MAJORITY LEADER HARRY
REID ADDRESSED COLLEAGUES
YESTERDAY.
>> I HAVE NEVER KNOWN ANYONE
LIKE DAN INOUYUE, NO ONE ELSE
HAS.
THE KINDNESS HE HAS SHOWN ME FOR
MY TIME HERE IN THE SENATE HAS
BEEN SOMETHING I WILL CHERISH
ALWAYS.
>> SENATOR INOUYE, SECOND
LONGEST SERVING MEMBER EVER
BEHIND ROBERT BYRD OF WEST
VIRGINIA.
>>> NEWTOWN HIGH SCHOOL FOOTBALL
COACH STEVEN GEORGE NEVER
EXPECTED A RESPONSE WHEN HE LEFT
A MESSAGE ON A WHITE BOARD FOR
PRESIDENT OBAMA THE PRESIDENT
VISITED NEWTOWN ON SUNDAY.
COACH GEORGE AND ANOTHER TEACHER
LEFT A NOTE ON THE WHITE BOARD
IN ADVANCE, THANKING HIM FOR
COMING.
THEY WEREN'T SURE THE COMMANDER
IN CHIEF WOULD SEE IT, BUT HE
DID.
THE COACH'S NOTE READ, DEAR
PRESIDENT OBAMA THE NEWTOWN
COMMUNITY IS SO THANKFUL THAT
ARE EVERY ARE YOU COMING TO HELP
US HEAL.
IN TIMES OF ADVERSITY, IT IS
REASSURING TO KNOW THAT WE HAVE
A STRONG LEADER TO HELP US
RECOVER.
THE PRESIDENT WROTE A NOTE BACK
ON THIS WHITE BOARD.
IT SAID SIMPLY YOU'RE IN OUR
THOUGHTS AND PRAYERS, BARACK
OBAMA.
HE TWEETED IT FOR EVERYONE TO
SEE.
>>> AHEAD ON "STARTING POINT," A
CALL FOR TIGHTER GUN CONTROL
LAWS WHAT DO PEOPLE DIRECTLY
AFFECTED THINK.
JOINING ME NEXT, LORI HAAS,
WHOSE DAUGHTER WAS SHOT AND
SURVIVED THE VIRGINIA TECH
MASSACRE.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
>>> SO AS FAMILIES IN NEWTOWN
CONTINUE TO GRIEVE, VICTIMS AND
SURVIVOR WHO'S EXPERIENCED PAST
SHOOTINGS ARE TRYING TO OFFER
COMFORT AND DEMAND CHANGE TO
PREVENT FUTURE KILLINGS LIKE
THESE.
A GROUP OF THEM JOINED MAYOR
BLOOMBERG ON MONDAY TO CALL FOR
IMMEDIATE AND NATIONAL ACTION ON
GUN CONTROL.
>> THIS IS JUST RIDICULOUS.
THIS IS AN OUTRAGE.
WE ARE KILLING EACH OTHER.
AND WE'RE THE ONLY
INDUSTRIALIZED COUNTRY IN THE
WORLD DOING IT.
>> JOINING ME NOW IS LORI HAAS,
MOTHER OF VIRGINIA TECH SHOOTING
SURVIVOR AND ADVOCATE OF THE
COALITION TO STOP GUN VIOLENCE.
THE FIRST QUESTION, HAVING LIVED
THROUGH THIS YOURSELF, WHEN YOU
SEE AN EVENT LIKE NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, ON FRIDAY, WHAT'S
YOUR FIRST REACTION?
>> SADNESS AND HORROR AND SHOCK,
AND, FRANKLY, VACILLATING
BETWEEN NAUSEA AND ANGER ON
FRIDAY WHEN WE HEARD THE NEWS.
IT WAS -- IT WAS DIFFICULT AT
BEST AND JUST UTMOST CONCERN FOR
THOSE WHO WERE INVOLVED IN THE
TRAGEDY AND WHOSE LOVED ONES
WERE KILLED BY A GUN.
>> YOU SAY NAUSEA AND ANGER.
WHERE IS THE ANGER DIRECTED?
>> FRANKLY, AT ELECTED LEADERS.
I FIND IT APPALLING THAT WE HAVE
ALLOWED THE GUN LOBBY TO LEAD
THE DEBATE ON POLICIES REGARDING
PUBLIC SAFETY.
I RELY ON LAW ENFORCEMENT AS THE
GUIDING PRINCIPAL FOR MY
DECISIONS ON PUBLIC SAFETY, AND
I TALK WITH THEM OFTEN AND I
HAVE SINCE THE SHOOTING IN APRIL
2007 WHERE MY DAUGHTER, EMILY,
WAS SHOT.
AND I BELIEVE THAT OUR PUBLIC
SAFETY OFFICIALS IN LAW
ENFORCEMENT SHOULD BE LEADING
THE DISCUSSION AND LEEGD THE AD
WAY ON THE POLICIES WE ENACT.
WE'VE LEARNED MUCH FROM THEM
AFTER THE VIRGINIA TECH
SHOOTING.
WE'D LIKE THEM TO BE THE LEAD
SPOKESMEN ON THE POLICY DEBATE.
NOT A GUN LOBBY OUT OF MAKE
MONEY.
>> YOU SAID YOU HAVE BEEN
WORKING ON THIS EVERY DAY SINCE
YOUR DAUGHTER WAS SHOT FIVE
YEARS AGO NOW.
MORE THAN FIVE YEARS AGO NOW.
>> YES.
>> IT'S BEEN A HARD EFFORT
CLEARLY.
DO YOU FEEL LIKE PEOPLE ARE
LISTENING?
WHY HAVEN'T THEY BEEN LISTENING?
>> A SEGMENT OF THE POPULATION
LISTENING.
A LARGE SEGMENT OF THE
POPULATION LISTENING.
IN POLLING, WE HAVE THE SUPPORT
OF NOT ONLY EVERY AMERICAN OUT
THERE VIRTUALLY, WE HAVE THE
SUPPORT OF NRA MEMBERS.
3 OUT OF 4 NRA MEMBERS WANT A
BACKGROUND CHECK ON ALL GUN
SALES.
THAT'S A CLEARLY AWARENESS BY
EVERYONE THAT WE NEED TO DO A
BETTER JOB WITH OUR GUN LAWS IN
THIS COUNTRY.
WHEN ALL OF AMERICA 3 OUT OF 4
NRA MEMBERS, 8 % 2% OF GUN OWNE
WANT MORE RESPONSIBLE GUN
CONTROL LAWS, LIKE A BACKGROUND
CHECK ON ALL GUN OWNERS, WE HAVE
THE MAJORITY AND LEADERS NEED TO
LISTEN TO US.
>> MAYOR BLOOMBERG, CLEARLY
FRUSTRATED.
HE IS ASKING PEOPLE TO DEMAND A
PLAN.
YOU HAVE BEEN PART OF THAT
EFFORT?
>> YES, I HAVE BEEN.
I AM DEMANDING A PLAN.
I AM SICKENED AND HORRIFIED AT
THE LEVEL OF CARNAGE IN THIS
COUNTRY, THAT THE EVERY DAY GUN
VIOLENCE, 34 AMERICANS SHOT BY
GUNS, THAT'S A VERY TECH EVERY
DAY AND NOW WE HAVE THE
UNSPEAKABLE HEARTACHE AND PAIN
OF THOSE FAMILIES WHO LOST LOVED
ONES, IN PARTICULAR 6 AND
7-YEAR-OLD CHILDREN.
I CANNOT FATHOM IT.
>> YOU MENTIONED BACKGROUND
CHECKS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA MET YESTERDAY
WITH SOME OF HIS KEY ADVISERS,
AND TASKED VICE PRESIDENT BIDEN
IN LEADING AN EFFORT TO COUP WI
NEW GUN LAWS.
WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE TO HAVE
HAPPEN?
>> I WOULD LIKE AN ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN REINSTATED.
THE BAN EXPIRED IN 2004.
SINCE THAT TIME, WE'VE HAD MASS
TRAGEDY AFTER MASS TRAGEDY WITH
HORRIFIC NUMBERS OF CARNAGE.
THE SHOOTER IN VIRGINIA TECH TO
USE A HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINE, 30
ROUNDS, ABLE TO DO JUST
UNSPEAKABLE NUMBERS.
WE'D LIKE STRICTER PENALTIES FOR
THOSE WHO TRAFFIC IN ILLEGAL
GUNS.
WE HAVE TO DO A BETTER JOB.
QUICK, EASY FIXES WE CAN DO NOW,
LITERALLY NOW TO START SAVING
LIVES IN AMERICA.
>> QUICKLY, IS THIS A TURNING
POINT?
>> I DO.
I ABSOLUTELY DO.
I'M CONVINCED OF IT.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
APPRECIATE YOUR EFFORTS.
THANKS VERY MUCH.
IF WOULD YOU LIKE TO HELP THOSE
AFFECTED BY THE SHOOTINGS, YOU
CAN GO TO CNN.COM/IMPACT.
>>> COMING UP NEXT, EXAMINING
WHY THE SHOOTER WENT ON THIS
RAMPAGE.
RESEARCH ON PREVIOUS MASS
SHOOTINGS MAY LINK THE BRAINS OF
THE KILLERS.
[ Female Announcer ]
RESEARCH SUGGESTS CELL HEALTH
PLAYS A KEY ROLE
THROUGHOUT OUR LIVES.
One A Day Women's 50+
IS A COMPLETE MULTIVITAMIN
DESIGNED FOR WOMEN'S HEALTH
CONCERNS AS WE AGE.
IT HAS 7 ANTIOXIDANTS
TO SUPPORT CELL HEALTH.
One A Day 50+.
>>> WELL COME BACK, EVERYONE.
YOU'RE WATCHING A SPECIAL
EDITION OF "STARTING POINT"
COMING FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
I AM ADAM LANZA'S MOTHER, A LINE
FROM A BLOG POST THAT HAS GONE
VIRAL, THE AUTHOR IS LIZA LONG,
SHE WRITES ABOUT THE
DIFFICULTIES OF HAVING A TEENAGE
SON WHO IS MENTALLY ILL.
>> SOMETIMES FOR NO APPARENT
REASON HE WILL TURN INTO THIS
ABSOLUTE RAGING, I DON'T KNOW
HOW TO DESCRIBE IT.
YOU'D HAVE TO SEE IT TO BELIEVE
IT.
I STOPPED AND SAID TO MYSELF,
YOU KNOW, THIS ISN'T NORMAL.
I HAVE TO FACE UP TO THE FACT
THAT I HAVE A SICK SON AND WE
NEED HELP.
>> Reporter: LIZA TELLS CNN SHE
LOVES HER SON BUT THAT
"TERRIFIES ME."
THERE ARE MANY QUESTIONS STILL
UNANSWERED ABOUT THE NEWTOWN
SCHOOL TRAGEDY, THE BIGGEST OF
COURSE IS WHY AND MAYBE THAT
WILL NEVER BE ANSWERED.
WHY DID THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER
HAVE FIRST GRADERS IN AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN HIS SIGHTS?
DR. SANJAY GUPTA TELLS US ON
PREVIOUS MASS MURDERERS,
POSSIBLE LOOK INSIDE THE VIOLENT
MIND.
>> Reporter: FIRST THING YOU
NOTICE WHEN YOU LOOK AROUND
NEWTOWN, EVERYONE HAS THAT
QUESTIONING LOOK, WHY?
WHAT DID WE MISS, IF ANYTHING?
NO ANSWERS YET, JUST HINDSIGHT.
TO TRY AND MAKE SOME SENSE OF
THE TRAGEDY HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, MEDICAL
INVESTIGATORS OFTEN LOOK FOR
EVIDENCE OF PATTERNS, NOT
TALKING ABOUT LOOKING AT
CLOTHING STYLES OR MUSICAL
PREFERENCES OR LIFESTYLE BUT
RATHER LOOKING FOR EVIDENCE OF
SPECIFIC PLANS, COULD GET SOME
CLUE AS TO WHAT WAS HAPPENING IN
THE PERSON'S MIND AND IN THEIR
BRAIN.
IT'S HARD TO KNOW, BECAUSE
THANKFULLY THERE ARE RELATIVELY
FEW TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS ONE BUT
A CLOSE LOOK AT TEN OF THE MOST
ANALYZED MASS MURDER CASES IN
HISTORY PROVIDE REMARKABLE
INSIGHT.
ACCORDING TO THIS RESEARCH
DOCTORS START BY PLACING THE
KILLERS INTO THREE CATEGORIES,
TRAUMATIZED, PSYCHOTIC,
PSYCHOPATHIC.
IN 2005 A 16-YEAR-OLD KILLED
NINE PEOPLE AT A SCHOOL IN
MINNESOTA.
LOOK INTO HIS PAST REVEALED AN
ABUSED BOY WITH AN AWFUL FAMILY
HISTORY.
THE SHOOTER HAD BEEN PREVIOUSLY
TRAUMATIZED.
THE VIRGINIA TECH SHOOTER KILLED
32 PEOPLE, SIX WERE MURDERED IN
ARIZONA AND 12 LIVES WERE TAKEN
IN AN AURORA, COLORADO, MOVIE
THEATER.
IN EACH CASE THE KILLERS SHOWS
SIGNED OF PSYCHOTIC BEHAVIOR,
SEVERE DELUSIONS AND PARANOIA.
ONE OF THE MURDERERS OF
COLUMBINE WAS LATER DISCOVERED
TO BE A TEXTBOOK PSYCHOPATH AND
HE EVEN LAUGHED WHILE GUNNING
DOWN HIS VICTIMS.
LOOKING BACK, NONE OF THEM HAD
SNAPPED.
THEY HAD ALL LEFT CLUES, PIECED
TOGETHER AFTER IT WAS TOO LATE.
HINDSIGHT.
WE STILL DON'T KNOW MUCH ABOUT
THE SHOOTER WHO LIVED IN THIS
HOME BUT THERE IS SOMETHING ELSE
TO CONSIDER, WHAT MEDICATIONS,
IF ANY, HE WAS ON, AND
SPECIFICALLY I'M TALKING ABOUT
ANTIDEPRESSANTS.
IF YOU LOOK AT THE STUDIES ON
OTHER SHOOTINGS LIKE THIS THAT
HAVE HAPPENED, MEDICATIONS LIKE
THIS WERE A COMMON FACTOR.
I WANT TO BE CLEAR, I'M NOT
SAYING THAT ANTIDEPRESSANTS
CAN'T BE EFFECTIVE BUT PEOPLE
SEEM TO AGREE THERE IS A
VULNERABLE TIME WHEN SOMEONE
STARTS THESE MEDICATIONS AND
WHEN SOMEONE STOPS COULD LEAD TO
INCREASED IMPULSIVITY, DECREASED
JUDGMENT, AND MAKING SOMEONE OUT
OF TOUCH.
NONE OF THIS IS AN EXCUSE AND
IT'S NEVER ONE THING.
NONE OF THE BEHAVIORS WILL FULLY
REDIKT OR EXPLAIN WHY BUT SOON
AGAIN THERE WILL BE HINDSIGHT
THAT MIGHT JUST HELP PREVENT
ANOTHER TRAGEDY.
DR. SANJAY GUPTA, CNN, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>>> AFTER SEVERAL MASS SHOOTINGS
IN A FEW SHORT SHORTS THE
NEWTOWN MASSACRE MIGHT BE THE
TIPPING POINT FOR WASHINGTON TO
ASK.
ARIZONA CONGRESSMAN RON BARBER
TOOK OVER GABRIELLE GIFFORDS'
SEAT AFTER THE SHOOTING.
WHY PRESIDENT OBAMA'S NEW
PROPOSAL COULD BE THE COMPROMISE
REPUBLICANS ARE LOOKING FOR.
THAT'S AHEAD.
PACK THE BIG TASTE
OF GRANOLA AND DARK CHOCOLATE
INTO ONE PERFECT SQUARE,
UNDER 100 CALORIES.
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA THINS.
MAKE A WISH!
I WISH WE COULD
LIE HERE FOREVER.
I WISH THIS TEST DRIVE WAS OVER,
SO WE COULD HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
TEST DRIVE!
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A JETTA.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN,
$0 DUE AT SIGNING, $0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
BUT I'M STILL STUBBED UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus Liquid Gels
SPEEDS RELIEF
TO YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A DECONGESTANT
FOR YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
THANKS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
WE'VE DECIDED TO
WE'RE ALL HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR IN THE GULF,
PUT ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
'CAUSE ALL OUR STATES ARE GREAT.
AND NOW IS WHEN THE GULF
GETS EVEN BETTER.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE OR
JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
ENJOY THE WILDLIFE
AND NATURAL BEAUTY.
AND DON'T FORGET
OUR AMAZING SEAFOOD.
SO COME TO THE GULF,
YOU'LL HAVE A GREAT TIME.
ESPECIALLY IN ALABAMA.
YOU MEAN MISSISSIPPI.
THAT'S FLORIDA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP AND ALL
OF US WHO CALL THE GULF HOME.
>>> THIS MORNING IN OUR SPECIAL
EDITION OF "STARTING POINT" GUN
CONTROL DEBATE IS NOW IN FULL
FORCE AS THE WHITE HOUSE
CONSIDERS CHANGES AND NATIONAL
POLLS SHOW A NEW ATTITUDE AFTER
THE NEWTOWN SHOOTING.
WILL THIS TRAGEDY INSPIRE
LAWMAKERS TO ACT?
HERE IN NEWTOWN WHILE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY REMAINS CLOSED, IT IS
STILL A CRIME SCENE, ALL OF THE
OTHER STUDENTS IN TOWN GO BACK
TO CLASS IN A COUPLE OF HOURS.
ANOTHER CHILD IS LAID TO REST
TODAY.
>>> YET ANOTHER SIGN THIS
MORNING THE TIDE MAY BE TURNING
OVER GUN CONTROL.
GUN COMPANY STOCKS UNDER FIRE AS
A BIG PENSION FUND MOVES TO
STRIP ITS INVESTMENTS.
>>> NEW DEVELOPMENTS ON THE
FISCAL CLIFF THIS MORNING, MAYBE
BIG ONES.
COULD THE PRESIDENT'S SURPRISING
NEW OFFER FINALLY SEAL THE DEAL
TO AVOID TAX HIKES FOR MOST
AMERICANS?
>>> IT'S TUESDAY, DECEMBER 18th,
AND A SPECIAL EDITION OF
"STARTING POINT" LIVE FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, BEGINS
RIGHT NOW.
GOOD MORNING, WELCOME BACK.
YOU'RE WATCHING A SPECIAL
EDITION OF "STARTING POINT" LIVE
FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WHERE
THE THIRD OF 20 MURDERED
CHILDREN WILL BE LAID TO REST
TODAY.
THE TRAGEDY IS REIGNITING THE
DEBATE OVER GUN CONTROL IN THE
COUNTRY AND LAWMAKERS MIGHT BE
READY TO TAKE ACTION.
PRESIDENT OBAMA MET WITH SENIOR
STAFF AND CABINET MEMBERS
YESTERDAY.
HE WANTS IDEAS INCLUDING
REINSTATING A BAN ON AUTOMATIC
WEAPONS.'S SPORTING GOODS HAS
SUSPENDED THE SALE OF AR-15
RIFLES AND OTHER GUNS LIKE IT.
IN FACT THE MODERN SPORTING
RIFLES SECTION OF ITS WEBSITE IS
BLANK THIS MORNING.
THE COMPANY SAYS OUT OF RESPECT
FOR THE VICTIMS AND THEIR
FAMILIES, WE'VE REMOVED ALL GUNS
IN OUR STORE NEAREST TO NEWTOWN
AND SUSPEND THE SALE OF MODERN
SPORTING RIFLES IN ALL OF OUR
STORES CHAINWIDE."
TODAY GRIEF COUNSELORS AND
POLICE WILL BE ON HAND WHEN THE
CHILDREN IN TOWN HEAD BACK TO
CLASS FOR THE FIRST TIME SINCE
FRIDAY.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IS
STILL A CRIME SCENE AND IT
REMAINS CLOSED.
JESSICA HAD A PASSION FOR
HORSES, AND THEY PROMISED HER
SHE WOULD GET A HORSE WHEN SHE
WAS 10 YEARS OLD.
SHE WAS JUST 6 YEARS OLD.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT ARIZONA GUN
LAWS WITH ARIZONA CONGRESSMAN
RON BARBER.
HE TOOK OVER GABBY GIFFORDS SEAT
AFTER THE SHOOTING IN TUCSON.
AT THE BOTTOM OF THE HOUR,
FORMER REPUBLICAN GOVERNOR OF
OKLAHOMA FRANK KEATING.
FIRST RIGHT TO JOHN BERMAN WITH
AN UPDATE ON OTHER STORIES
MAKING NEWS.
>>> NEW DRAMATIC DEVELOPMENTS A
REPORTER AND HIS CREW HELD FOR
FIVE DAYS IN SYRIA NOW FREE
UNHARMED.
NBC SAYING ITS CHIEF FOREIGN
CORRESPONDENT RICHARD ENGEL IS
SAFE, UNHARMED AND OUT OF THE
COUNTRY.
MOMENTS AGO HE DETAILED HIS
HARROWING ESCAPE ON NBC'S
"TODAY" SHOW.
>> AT THE END OF THIS WE WERE
BEING MOVED TO YET ANOTHER
LOCATION AROUND 11:00 LAST NIGHT
LOCAL TIME AND AS WE WERE MOVING
ALONG THE ROAD THE KIZ NDNAPPER
CAME ACROSS A REBEL CHECKPOINT,
SOMETHING THEY DIDN'T EXPECT AND
WE WERE IN A MINI VAN AND AS WE
WERE DRIVING ALONG THE ROAD THE
KIDNAPPERS SAW THE CHECKPOINT,
STARTED A GUNFIGHT, TWO OF THE
KIDNAPPERS WERE KILLED, WE
CLIMBED OUT OF THE VEHICLE AND
THE REBELS TOOK US, WE SPENT THE
NIGHT WITH THEM, WE DIDN'T GET
MUCH SLEEP.
>> WE ARE SO GLAD THEY'RE ALL
SAFE.
ENGEL SAYS HIS KIDNAPPERS WERE
GOVERNMENT MILITIA CALLED THE
SHABIHAT TRAINED BY IRAN'S
REVOLUTIONARY GUARD, WITH
HEZBOLLAH.
SYRIAN OPPOSITION FIGHTERS
RESCUED A DIFFERENT TURKISH
REPORTER WORKING FOR NBC
KIDNAPPED LAST WEDNESDAY.
TODAY CONGRESS WILL RECEIVE A
REPORT ON THE ATTACK ON
BENGHAZI.
THE REPORT WAS ORDERED BY
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON ALTHOUGH SHE WILL NOT
TESTIFY.
SHE OF COURSE IS RECOVERING FROM
A CONCUSSION.
THE ATTACK IN SEPTEMBER KILLED
FOUR AMERICANS INCLUDING CHRIS
STEVENS, THE U.S. AMBASSADOR TO
LIBYA.
>>> NEGOTIATIONS MAY BE SHOWING
SIGNS OF HOPE WITH TWO WEEKS TO
GO.
PRESIDENT OBAMA PRESENTED A NEW
PROPOSAL TO HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER.
TAX RATES GOING UP ON INCOMES OF
PEOPLE HIGHER THAN $400,000.
THIS IS A CHANGE.
PREVIOUSLY HE WANTED TAXES
HIGHER ON HOUSEHOLDS AT
$250,000.
HE'S OFFERING NEW SPENDING CUTS
SAID TO BE WORTH ABOUT $200
BILLION AND FOR HIS PART INSTEAD
OF NO NEW TAXES WHERE THE
SPEAKER HAD BEEN FOR A LONG TIME
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER IS CALLING
FOR TAX HIKES ON PEOPLE MAKING
MORE THAN $1 MILLION.
HE HAS A BIG DAY TODAY MEETING
WITH HOUSE REPUBLICAN MEMBERS TO
UPDATE THEM ON NEGOTIATIONS THAT
COULD BE A LITTLE BIT OF A
DIFFICULT MEETING FOR HIM.
LET'S GO TO WASHINGTON TO GET AN
UPDATE ON THE TALKS.
CNN'S DAN LOTHIAN IS THERE.
>> Reporter: HELLO.
YOU'RE RIGHT, THIS COULD BE A
DIFFICULT MEETING FOR SPEAKER
JOHN BOEHNER AS HE TRIES TO SELL
THIS PROPOSAL TO HOUSE
REPUBLICANS.
THIS IS A DRAMATIC TURN OF
EVENTS BECAUSE PRESIDENT OBAMA
AS YOU POINTED OUT HAD BEEN
DIGGING IN HIS HEELS SAYING
THERE COULD NOT BE A DEAL UNLESS
TAXES WENT UP FOR HOUSE HOLDS
MAKING MORE THAN $250,000 AND
NOW THE PRESIDENT RAISING THAT
TO 400,000 SO CERTAINLY SOME
INDICATION AT LEAST ACCORDING TO
HOUSE REPUBLICAN THIS IS IS
MOVING IN THE RIGHT DIRECTION.
IN ADDITION THE PRESIDENT
CALLING FOR $1.2 TRILLION IN NEW
REVENUE, ALSO $1.2 TRILLION IN
SPENDING CUTS AND THIS MEETS THE
DEMAND THAT SPEAKER BOEHNER HAD,
THAT THERE HAD TO BE AN EQUAL
AMOUNT OF SPENDING, AND ALSO
REVENUE, BUT THEY STILL DON'T
BELIEVE THAT THE MATH REALLY
ADDS UP HERE.
SPOKESMAN FOR SPEAKER BOEHNER'S
OFFICE, BRENDAN BUCK SAYING A
PROPOSAL THAT INCLUDES $1.3
TRILLION IN REVENUE FOR ONLY
$930 BILLION IN SPENDING CUTS
CANNOT BE CONSIDERED BALANCED.
SO WHILE THIS IS A MAJOR
DEVELOPMENT HERE, STILL SOME
DISAGREEMENTS.
THE WHITE HOUSE AT LEAST SOURCES
POINTING OUT THE WHITE HOUSE
SAYING THAT THIS IS NOT THE
FINAL OFFER, SO SUGGESTING THERE
COULD BE ADDITIONAL COMPROMISE
AHEAD.
>> YOU SAW CRITICISM FROM THE
RIGHT FROM BRENDAN BUCK, JUST
WHAT YOU WERE SAYING.
PRESIDENT OBAMA COULD FACE SOME
HEAT FROM THE LEFT BECAUSE HE'S
OFFERING CONCESSIONS THAT COULD
RELATE TO SOME ENTITLEMENT CUTS
WHEN YOU GET INTO THE COST OF
LIVING INDEXES, CORRECT?
>> THAT IS CORRECT.
WHEN THE ARGUMENT FROM DEMOCRATS
IN THE PRESIDENT'S PARTY ON THE
LEFT HAS BEEN THAT THE PRESIDENT
HAS BEEN TOO AGGRESSIVE WHEN IT
COMES TO SPENDING CUTS SO
SOMETHING LIKE THIS COULD ADD
ADDITIONAL PRESSURE TO THE
PRESIDENT'S SIDE IN THIS DEBATE,
BUT AGAIN, THE PRESIDENT HAS
MOVED.
HE'S TRYING TO REACH SOME KIND
OF AGREEMENT HERE SO THEY CAN
PREVENT THAT FISCAL CLIFF FROM
HAPPENING, AS THAT CLOCK WINDS
DOWN.
IT APPEARS THAT BOTH SIDES MUCH
CLOSER TOGETHER NOW BUT STILL A
LITTLE WAYS TO GO.
>> DAN, TODAY A BIG DAY WHEN
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER FACES THE
REPUBLICAN CAUCUS OF THE HOUSE.
DAN LOTHIAN IN WASHINGTON THANK
YOU VERY MUCH.
>>> HE WAS A WITNESS TO PEARL
HARBOR, EARNED THE CONGRESSIONAL
MEDAL OF HONOR, TRIBUTES POURING
IN FOR DANIEL INOUYE.
HE DIED YESTERDAY AT THE AGE OF
88, THE SECOND LONGEST SERVING
MEMBER EVER BEYOND THE LATE
SENATOR ROBERT BYRD OF WEST
VIRGINIA.
FORMER VET BOB DOLAN SAID
"SENATOR INOUYE WAS ONE OF THE
SENATE'S GIANTS.
HE BELIEVED IN CIVILITY AND
COMPROMISE WHEN NECESSARY AND HE
WAS A GOOD, GOOD FRIEND."
SENATOR DOLE AND INOUYE LONG
BEFORE THEY WERE BOTH SENATORS
WERE IN A MILITARY HOSPITAL FOR
ALMOST TWO YEARS TOGETHER IN
MICHIGAN WHILE THEY WERE BOTH
RECOVERING FROM THEIR INJURIES
FROM WORLD WAR II.
TWO GREAT FRIENDS.
SOLEDAD BACK TO YOU IN NEWTOWN.
>> MY GOODNESS AND THE STORY OF
WHAT HE DID, WHAT HAPPENED WHEN
HE LOST HIS ARM AND HOW HE WAS
ABLE TO SAVE HIMSELF IN WORLD
WAR II, THAT IS AN INCREDIBLE
STORY.
THANKS, JOHN, APPRECIATE IT.
>>> THE HORROR OF NEWTOWN BRINGS
TO MIND SO MANY OTHER SHOOTINGS,
THE ASSASSINATION ATTEMPT ON
ARIZONA CONGRESSWOMAN GABBY GIVE
FORDS, JANUARY 8th OF 2011 AND
LEFT SIX PEOPLE DEAD.
AMONG THOSE WOUNDED WAS RON
BARBER, GIFFORDS DISTRICT
DIRECTOR.
HE TOOK DOWN WHEN SHE STEPPED
DOWN.
HE WON A FULL TERM LAST MONTH.
CONGRESSMAN BARBER THANK YOU FOR
BEING WITH US.
>> GOOD MORNING, THANK YOU FOR
HAVING ME ON.
>> IT'S MY PLEASURE.
WHAT WAS IT LIKE TO HEAR ABOUT
THIS TRAGEDY?
IT'S NOT EVEN BEEN TWO YEARS
SINCE THE SHOOTING THAT INJURED
YOU AND INJURED GABBY GIFFORDS.
DOES IT JUST TAKE YOU BACK TO
THAT DAY TO ALMOST TWO YEARS
AGO?
>> YES, IT DID, AND IT DID FOR
MY WHOLE FAMILY, PARTICULARLY MY
GRANDCHILDREN, WHO WERE AFFECTED
THEN, AND I THINK EVEN MORE
PROFOUNDLY AFFECTED THIS TIME,
KNOWING THAT CHILDREN THEIR AGE
WERE KILLED IN NEWTOWN AND I
JUST WANT TO SAY THAT THE
COMMUNITY OF TUCSON IS JUST
HEARTSICK OVER WHAT HAPPENED IN
NOUN.
WE GATHERED TOGETHER ON SUNDAY
NIGHT IN A CANDLELIGHT VIGIL TO
PRAY FOR AND TO SEND OUR BEST
WISHES TO THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN,
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN, AS THEY
WERE BACK IN JANUARY 8th, 2011.
WE WANT THEM TO KNOW WE ARE WITH
THEM AND WE UNDERSTAND PROBABLY
BETTER THAN MOST COMMUNITIES
WHAT THEY'RE GOING THROUGH.
>> UNFORTUNATELY AND SADLY THAT
IS PROBABLY TRUE.
THE PRESIDENT ASKED HIS CABINET
TO COME UP WITH SOME IDEAS ABOUT
HOW THEY CAN CHANGE GUN LAWS.
YOU'RE A SECOND AMENDMENT
SUPPORTER.
WHAT KIND OF LAWS WOULD YOU
DRAFT, IF GIVEN THE OPPORTUNITY?
>> I AM A SUPPORTER OF THE
SECOND AMENDMENT.
I BELIEVE IT'S ONE OF THOSE
RIGHTS THAT WE HAVE TO PROTECT
BUT I BELIEVE IT'S TIME FOR US
TO MOVE IN A DIFFERENT DIRECTION
WITH REGARD TO ASSAULT WEAPONS,
EXTENDED CLIPS, MAGAZINES WITH
INCREDIBLE FIRE POWER.
THE YOUNG MAN THAT SHOT THOSE OF
US IN TUCSON LAST YEAR WAS
CARRYING CLIPS THAT HAD 30
ROUNDS IN THEM AND IN A MATTER
OF ALMOST 45 SECONDS HE WAS ABLE
TO UNLOAD ALL OF THOSE BULLETS
AND SHOT 19 PEOPLE, SIX OF THEM
DIED.
I DON'T BELIEVE WE CAN CONTINUE
TO HAVE THOSE KINDS OF WEAPONS
AVAILABLE AND ESPECIALLY IN THE
HANDS OF SOMEONE WHO IS MENTALLY
ILL AS HE WAS AND SEEMS LIKE ALL
THE OTHER SHOOTERS IN THE LAST
COUPLE YEARS HAVE HAD A
DIAGNOSIS OF SERIOUS MENTAL
ILLNESS.
I JUST WANT TO SAY I KNOW FROM
MY EXPERIENCE IN WORKING IN THE
FIELD OF MENTAL HEALTH FOR 32
YEARS THAT VERY FEW PEOPLE WITH
MENTAL ILLNESS ARE VIOLENT
PEOPLE BUT SOME ARE, ESPECIALLY
IF THEY'RE NOT TREATED, SO WE
HAVE TO DO BOTH.
WE HAVE TO GO AFTER THE WEAPON
POWER, THE FIREPOWER, AND WE
ALSO HAVE TO MAKE SURE THAT WE
HAVE BETTER SERVICES FOR PEOPLE
WITH MENTAL ILLNESS AND
SUPPORTING THEIR FAMILIES.
>> GOING TO THE ASSAULT WEAPONS,
IS IT FAR ENOUGH OR SHOULD YOU
BE FOCUSING WHEN IT COMES TO GUN
LEGISLATION AND GUN CONTROL,
SHOULD IT BE ON THE 30-ROUND
CLIPS?
SHOULD IT BE THE ASSAULT
WEAPONS?
IF YOU LOOK AT THE OVERALL GUN
VIOLENCE, 80% IS CAUSED BY
HANDGUNS OR ATTRIBUTED TO
HANDGUN VIOLENCE SO IS THAT
LEAVING OUT A MAJOR PORTION IN
THE DEBATE, AND WHAT IS THE
LEGISLATION THAT COULD ACTUALLY
MAKE CHANGE AND WOULD AFFECT A
LOT OF PEOPLE?
>> I THINK FIRST OF ALL WE HAVE
TO BE REALISTIC ABOUT WHAT
POSSIBLY CAN BE DONE.
I'VE HEARD OVER THE LAST FEW
DAYS SOME PEOPLE WHO ARE HEAVILY
SUPPORTED BY THE NRA COME OUT
SAYING FINALLY WE HAVE TO DO
SOMETHING AND WE'RE GOING TO
LOOK AT LEGISLATION REGARDING
ASSAULT WEAPONS, MILITARY STYLE
WEAPONS AND EXTENDED CLIPS, AS I
SAY, HAVE LOTS OF BULLETS IN
THEM THAT CAN DO SERIOUS HARM IN
A VERY SHORT PERIOD OF TIME.
HANDGUN IS SOMETHING ELSE.
I THINK I'M AFTER A LEGISLATION,
I WANT TO SEE LEGISLATION
ENACTED THAT TAKES AWAY THE
AVAILABILITY OF THESE KINDS OF
WEAPONS THAT CAN DO SO MUCH HARM
AND SUCH A SHORT PERIOD OF TIME.
IN TEN MINUTES, THE SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT WAS COMPLETED, AND
26 PEOPLE DIED, INCLUDING 20
LITTLE ONES.
FOR ME AS A MEMBER OF CONGRESS,
AS A PERSON WHO HAS BEEN THROUGH
A SHOOTING TRAGEDY WHERE THIS
EXTENDED CLIP ISSUE WAS PRESENT
AND AS A GRANDFATHER I HAVE TO
STAND UP AND BE COUNTED ON THIS.
I'LL DO EVERYTHING I CAN TO MAKE
SURE WE LIMIT THE FIRE POWER AND
GET SERVICES TO PEOPLE WITH
MENTAL ILLNESS.
WE HAVE TO DO BOTH.
>> THOSE TWO THINGS ARE BOTH
GIANT AND I THINK EVERYONE WOULD
SAY THE MENTAL HEALTH PART OF IT
IS COMPLETELY UNDERFUNDED.
IS IT POSSIBLE TO MAKE CHANGE
AND DISCUSS THOSE THINGS
TOGETHER, RIGHT?
OFTEN I THINK GUN ADVOCATES WILL
SAY WELL IT'S PEOPLE WHO HAVE
MENTAL PROBLEMS WE SHOULD BE
FOCUSING ON AND THERE ARE OTHERS
WHO SAY LISTEN IT'S THE WEAPONS
ON THE STREET WE SHOULD BE
FOCUSING ON.
IS THERE A WAY TO TALK ABOUT
BOTH AT THE SAME TIME AND MAKE
TANGIBLE CHANGE?
>> I THINK WE HAVE NO CHOICE.
WHEN WE LOOK AT THE MASS
SHOOTINGS SINCE JANUARY 8th,
THERE IS TWO ASPECTS OF THOSE
SHOOTINGS THAT THEY ALL HAVE IN
COMMON.
SOMEONE THE FIRE POWER, ASSAULT
WEAPON, MILITARY STYLE WEAPONS
AND EXTENDED CLIPS OF MAGAZINES
THAT CARRY A LOT OF ROUNDS.
THE OTHER IS UNTREATED AND IN
SOME CASES UNDIAGNOSED SERIOUS
MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES.
WE NEED TO GO AFTER BOTH OF
THESE ISSUES AND WE NEED TO DO
THEM IN TANDEM.
ULTIMATELY I IMAGINE THEY'LL GET
SEPARATED BUT FOR ME THEY GO
HAND IN HAND AND WE HAVE TO DO
BOTH.
>> CONGRESSMAN RON BARBER
JOINING US.
NICE TO TALK TO YOU, SIR, NICE
TO SEE YOU.
APPRECIATE YOUR TIME THIS
MORNING.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> YOU BET.
>>> STILL AHEAD ON "STARTING
POINT" STUDENTS IN NEWTOWN ARE
GOING BACK TO SCHOOL THIS
MORNING.
WE'LL TELL YOU HOW THE COMMUNITY
IS PREPARING FOR THAT COMING UP
NEXT IN A LIVE REPORT.
WE LEAVE YOU WITH WHAT WAS A
REALLY NICE TRIBUTE THAT WE SAW
FROM THE JUDGES AND THE
CONTESTANTS OF "THE VOICE"
REMEMBERING THE VICTIMS OF THIS
MASSACRE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
♪ HALLELUJAH
♪ I DID MY BEST, AND IT WASN'T
MUCH ♪
♪ I COULDN'T FEEL SO I TRIED TO
TOUCH ♪
♪ I TOLD THE TRUTH, I DIDN'T
HAVE TO FOOL YOU ♪
IT'S LIKE BEING NESTLED
IN AN EIGHT-WAY, ADJUSTABLE,
HEATED AND VENTILATED SEAT
SURROUNDED BY A 500-WATT
SOUND SYSTEM
WHILE FLOATING ON A SUSPENSION
MADE OF BILLOWY CLOUDS.
OR YOU COULD JUST HAND THEM
YOUR KEYS.
♪
SFX- "sounds of african
drum and flute"
Look who's back.
Again?
It's embarrassing
It's embarrassing!
We can see you Carl.
We can totally see you.
Come on you're better than
this...all that prowling around.
Yeah, you're the
king of the jungle.
Have you thought about going
vegan Carl?
HAHAHA!!
You know folks who save hundreds
of dollars by
switching to GEICO
sure are happy.
How happy are they Jimmy?
Happier than antelope with
night-vision goggles.
Nice!
Get happy. Get GEICO.
>>> HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL REMAINS
CLOSED.
IT IS AN ACTIVE CRIME SCENE.
STUDENTS AT THAT SCHOOL WILL GO
BACK TO CLASS EVENTUALLY ABOUT
SEVEN MILES AWAY AT CHALK HILL
SCHOOL.
FOR THOSE RETURNING STUDENTS AND
FAMILIES, IT IS BACK TO A
PRODUCTIVE ROUTINE, ONE THAT'S
NOW FILLED UNFORTUNATELY WITH
ANXIETY AND PAIN AS WELL.
CNN'S SANDRA ENDOHAS OUR REPORT
THIS MORNING.
>> Reporter: IN THE WAKE OF
TRAGEDY A STEP TOWARDS NORMALCY,
THAT MEANS GOING BACK TO SCHOOL.
>> WE ARE ALSO GOING TO BE A
LITTLE BIT WORRIED BECAUSE WE
KNOW WHAT WE THOUGHT WAS A
SECURE SCHOOL HAD THIS HAPPEN TO
THEM.
>> Reporter: BUT FACING FEAR MAY
BE THE FIRST STEP TO OVERCOME
THIS TRAGEDY.
>> CHILDREN HAVE TO GET BACK TO
SCHOOL.
IF WE LET THIS SORT OF TERROR IN
OUR LIVES ANYWHERE IN THIS
COUNTRY, THEN WE HAVE LOST.
WE'VE GOT TO GET OUR KIDS BACK
TO SCHOOL AGAIN.
>> Reporter: CLASSES ARE
RESUMING FOR 35,400 STUDENTS IN
THE DISTRICT EXCEPT FOR THOSE AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
MONDAY ALL SCHOOLS WERE CLOSED
AS TEACHERS AND ADMINISTRATORS
TRAINED WITH EXPERTS ON HOW TO
HANDLE THE AFTERMATH.
MANY PARENTS WE SPOKE WITH AGREE
KIDS BELONG BACK IN SCHOOL.
>> I THINK THAT ONE OF THE BIG
THINGS THAT WE HAVE TO DO IS
HAVE SOME SORT OF NORMALCY, AND
SCHOOL IS PART OF THAT.
>> UNFORTUNATELY YOU KNOW WE'RE
LIVING IN THIS WORLD WHERE
SOMETIMES EVIL PREVAILS
SOMETIMES, BUT WE'RE JUST
BELIEVING THAT GOOD WILL
OVERCOME THIS.
>> Reporter: SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY REMAINS A CRIME
SCENE.
FURNITURE AND SUPPLIES WERE
MOVED TO CHUCK HILL MIDDLE
SCHOOL IN NEIGHBORING MONROE
WILL SANDY HOOK STUDENTS WILL
EVENTUALLY RESUME CLASSES.
>> WHEN THE CHILDREN COME IN,
WHENEVER THE SCHOOL IS STARTED
THEY'LL WALK INTO A CLASSROOM
THAT LOOKS AS CLOSE AS POSSIBLE
AS THEIR CLASSROOM THAT THEY
LEFT.
>> Reporter: POLICE OFFICERS
WILL BE PRESENT AT NEWTOWN
SCHOOLS AND PRINCIPALS HAVE
ASKED PARENTS TO MAKE SURE THEY
TALK TO THEIR CHILDREN ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED HERE BEFORE THEIR
KID GOES BACK TO SCHOOL AND
TEACHERS WILL ALSO BE TALKING
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED IN AN
AGE-APPROPRIATE MANNER.
SOLEDAD?
>> SAN DA ENDO FOR US THIS
MORNING, THANK YOU.
>>> NEW FALLOUT OF THE TRAGEDY
TO TALK ABOUT, AND IT'S CERTAIN
TO ADD FUEL TO THE GUN CONTROL
DEBATE, TELL YOU WHAT'S
HAPPENING TO STOCK IN GUN
COMPANIES UP NEXT WITH CHRISTINE
ROMANS.
STAY WITH US.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
low-cost investment options--
like our Exchange
Traded Funds, or ETFs
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
which now have the lowest
operating expenses
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
in their respective
Lipper categories.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Lower than SPDR
and even lower than Vanguard.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
That means with Schwab,
your portfolio has
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
a better chance to grow.
And you can trade
all our ETFs online,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
commission-free, from your
Schwab account.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
So let's talk about
saving money,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
with Schwab ETFs.
Schwab ETFs now have the lowest
operating expenses
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
in their respective
Lipper categories.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Call 1-800-4SCHWAB
or visit Schwab.com
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
to open an account today.
Funding is easy
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
with Schwab Mobile Deposit.
Investors should consider
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
carefully information
D#: 1-800-345-2550
contained in the prospectus,
cluding investment objectives,
D#: 1-800-345-2550
risks, charges, and expenses.
You can obtain
D#: 1-800-345-2550
a prospectus by visiting
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
w.schwab.com/schwabetfs.
Please read the prospectus
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
carefully before investing.
Well, it's that time of year
again.
You know, picture-taking season.
And with Photo Stream,
You can share all the photos you
want,
With just the people you want.
It's as easy as pie.
Mmmm .. pie.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO "STARTING
POINT."
INTERESTING NEW FALLOUT IN THE
WAKE OF THE SHOOTINGS IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
IT HAS TO DO WITH THE MONEY, THE
FINANCING BEHIND THE GUN
INDUSTRY.
>> BIG PRIVATE EQUITY FIRM THAT
OWNS THE COMPANY THAT MAKES
BUSHMASTER FIREARMS, THE RIFLE
USED IN THE ATTACK SAYING IT'S
GOING TO SELL THAT COMPANY.
LOOK AT THE MONEY HERE BEHIND
BUSHMASTER.
THE CALIFORNIA STATE TEACHERS
RETIREMENT SYSTEM PUT IN
MULTIMILLION-DOLLAR INTO A FUND
CREATED BY CERBERUS CAPITAL
MANAGEMENT WHICH CREATED THE
FREEDOM GROUP, A COMBINATION OF
TEN AMMUNITION AND GUNMAKERS.
THEY'RE THE FLOW.
THIS MORNING WHAT YOU HEAR FROM
CERBERUS CAPITAL THEY'RE GOING
TO SELL FREEDOM GROUP.
"IT IS APPARENT THAT THE SANDY
HOOK TRAGEDY WAS A WATERSHED
EVENT THAT HAS RAISED THE
NATIONAL DEBATE ON GUN CONTROL
TO AN UNPRECEDENT THE LEVEL.
IT IS NOT OUR ROLE TO TAKE
POSITIONS OR ATTEMPT TO SHAPE OR
INFLUENCE THE GUN CONTROL POLICY
DEBATE.
THERE ARE HOWEVER ACTIONS THAT
WE AS A FIRM CAN TAKE."
CALIFORNIA TEACHERS INDIRECTLY
THROUGH THEIR RETIREMENT FUND
OWN MORE THAN 6% OF BUSHMASTERS,
TEACHERS OWN MORE THAN 6% OF
BUSHMASTER, THE COMPANY THAT
MADE THE RIFLE USED IN THAT
ATTACK ON THE SCHOOL.
THIS SAY STATEMENT, "THERE ARE A
LOT OF PRODUCTS THAT CAN BE USED
RESPONSIBLY OR IRRESPONSIBLY.
IN THIS CASE IT WAS USED
IRRESPONSIBLY.
NOW THAT A TRAGIC EVENT LIKE
THIS HAS OCCURRED I'M SURE IT IS
SOMETHING THAT WE WILL BE
DISCUSSING GOING FORWARD."
ON FRIDAY WHEN THIS WAS
UNFOLDING I GOOGLED BUSHMASTER
223, THE FIRST RESPONSE WAS TO
WALMART SAYING I TO GO TO THE
CARNEY, NEW JERSEY, STORE, TO
GET IT.
YOU COULDN'T GET IT ON LINE.
IT SAYS IT AIMS STRAIGHT AND
TRUE.
TODAY YOU CANNOT SEE THE
ADVERTISEMENT ON WALMART.COM.
WALMART SAYS THE GUN IS STILL
AVAILABLE IN SELECT STORES, IT'S
NOT ADVERTISING IT ONLINE.'S
SPORTING GOODS SUSPEND SELLING
WEAPONS LIKE THIS FOR NOW AND
CLOSED, NO MORE GUNS AT DICK'S
SPORTING GOODS CLOSEST TO
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> IT'S INTERESTING WITH
CERBERUS, THEY'RE A PRIVATE
EQUITY FIRM, THEIR BUSINESS IS
TO MAKE MONEY AND THEY'VE
DECIDED IT'S BAD BUSINESS TO BE
IN THE GUN BUSINESS.
>> THEY'VE HIRED SOMEBODY TO
HELP THEM SELL THE COMPANY.
THIS SAY BIG, IMPORTANT PRIVATE
EQUITY FIRM AND PRIVATE MEANS
PRIVATE, THEY BUY STUFF FOR
PROFIT NOT MEANT TO, THEY TRY TO
TAKE THIS COMPANY PUBLIC A
COUPLE YEARS AGO AND THEN
DECIDED NOT TO, PUT TOGETHER
WITH THIS COMPANY TEN OTHERS TO
MAKE A WHOLE FREEDOM GROUP, A
WHOLE GUNS AND AMMUNITION
BUSINESS TRYING TO GET OUT OF
THAT BUSINESS.
>> CHRISTINE ROMANS THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
>>> AHEAD WE'LL DISCUSS HOW GUN
POLICY WILL MOVE FORWARD WITH
FORMER OKLAHOMA GOVERNOR FRANK
KEATING, A MEMBER OF THE NRA.
HE GUIDED HIS STATE THROUGH THE
OKLAHOMA CITY BOMBING WHERE 19
CHILDREN WERE KILLED.
>>> IS PRESIDENT OBAMA'S NEW
PROPOSAL ON THE FISCAL CLIFF THE
DEAL REPUBLICANS WERE LOOKING
FOR?
JUST HOW CLOSE ARE WE NOW TO
AVOIDING THOSE MASSIVE ACROSS
THE BOARD TAX HIKES AND MAMMOTH
SPENDING CUTS?
WE'LL TALK ABOUT THAT COMING UP
NEXT.
ALL WAKING UP.
♪
BECOMING
PART OF THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
TREES WILL TALK TO NETWORKS
WILL TALK TO SCIENTISTS
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE.
CARS WILL TALK TO ROAD SENSORS
WILL TALK TO STOPLIGHTS
ABOUT TRAFFIC EFFICIENCY.
THE AMBULANCE WILL TALK
TO PATIENT RECORDS
WILL TALK TO DOCTORS
ABOUT SAVING LIVES.
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
THE NEXT BIG THING?
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
♪
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
♪
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
A BODY AT REST
TENDS TO STAY AT REST...
WHILE A BODY IN MOTION
TENDS TO STAY IN MOTION.
STAYING ACTIVE CAN ACTUALLY
EASE ARTHRITIS SYMPTOMS.
BUT IF YOU HAVE ARTHRITIS,
STAYING ACTIVE
CAN BE DIFFICULT.
PRESCRIPTION CELEBREX
CAN HELP RELIEVE ARTHRITIS PAIN
SO YOUR BODY
CAN STAY IN MOTION.
BECAUSE JUST ONE
200MG CELEBREX A DAY
CAN PROVIDE 24 HOUR RELIEF
FOR MANY WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND INFLAMMATION.
PLUS, IN CLINICAL STUDIES,
CELEBREX IS PROVEN TO IMPROVE
DAILY PHYSICAL FUNCTION
SO MOVING IS EASIER.
CELEBREX CAN BE TAKEN WITH
OR WITHOUT FOOD.
AND IT'S NOT A NARCOTIC.
YOU AND YOUR DOCTOR
SHOULD BALANCE THE BENEFITS
WITH THE RISKS.
ALL PRESCRIPTION NSAIDS,
LIKE CELEBREX, IBUPROFEN,
NAPROXEN, AND MELOXICAM
HAVE THE SAME
CARDIOVASCULAR WARNING.
THEY ALL MAY INCREASE
THE CHANCE
OF HEART ATTACK OR STROKE,
WHICH CAN LEAD TO DEATH.
THIS CHANCE INCREASES
IF YOU HAVE HEART DISEASE
OR RISK FACTORS
SUCH AS HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE
OR WHEN NSAIDS ARE TAKEN
FOR LONG PERIODS.
NSAIDS, INCLUDING CELEBREX,
INCREASE THE CHANCE OF SERIOUS
SKIN OR ALLERGIC REACTIONS
OR STOMACH AND INTESTINE
PROBLEMS,
SUCH AS BLEEDING AND ULCERS,
WHICH CAN OCCUR WITHOUT WARNING
AND MAY CAUSE DEATH.
PATIENTS ALSO TAKING ASPIRIN
AND THE ELDERLY
ARE AT INCREASED RISK FOR
STOMACH BLEEDING AND ULCERS.
DO NOT TAKE CELEBREX IF YOU'VE
HAD AN ASTHMA ATTACK, HIVES,
OR OTHER ALLERGIES TO ASPIRIN,
NSAIDS OR SULFONAMIDES.
GET HELP RIGHT AWAY IF YOU HAVE
SWELLING OF THE FACE OR THROAT,
OR TROUBLE BREATHING.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
YOUR MEDICAL HISTORY
AND FIND AN ARTHRITIS TREATMENT
FOR YOU.
VISIT CELEBREX.COM AND ASK
YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT CELEBREX.
FOR A BODY IN MOTION.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO "STARTING
POINT" COMING TO YOU LIVE FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WHERE A
GUNMAN'S RAMPAGE REIGNITED THE
GUN CONTROL DEBATE IN THIS
COUNTRY.
OVERNIGHT DICK'S SPORTING GOODS
OUT OF RESPECT OF THE VICTIMS IS
PULLING ALL GUNS FROM ITS STORE
CLOSE TOAST NEWTOWN AND
SUSPENDING THE SALE OF AR-15
GUNS AND WEAPONS LIKE IT ACROSS
THE MORE THAN 400 STORES OF THE
CHAIN.
PRESIDENT OBAMA MET WITH MEMBERS
OF THE CABINET AND WANTS TO COME
UP WITH VARIOUS GUN LAW CHANGES.
NEARLY 5,000 CHILDREN IN NEWTOWN
WILL HEAD BACK TO SCHOOL AFTER
THE FRIDAY SHOOTING.
SANDY HOOK WILL REMAIN CLOSED.
6-YEAR-OLD JESSICA REKOS, ONE OF
20 CHILDREN KILLED ON FRIDAY
WILL BE BURIED TODAY.
WHEN YOU HAVE A TRAGEDY OF THIS
MAGNITUDE YOU CANNOT HELP BUT
RECALL OTHER TRAGEDIES OF THE
PAST, SENSELESS ACTS THAT
CLAIMED INNOCENT LIVES IN THE
COUNTRY.
OKLAHOMA CITY BOMBING IN 1995,
THE BOMBING OF A FEDERAL
BUILDING DOWNTOWN KILLED 168
PEOPLE, AND 19 OF THEM WERE
CHILDREN.
FRANK KEATING WAS THE GOVERNOR
OF OKLAHOMA WHEN THAT HAPPENED
AND GOVERNOR KEATING JOINS THUS
MORNING.
NICE TO HAVE YOU WITH US, SIR.
WE APPRECIATE IT.
>> GOOD MORNING, SOLEDAD.
>> I HAVE TO IMAGINE -- GOOD
MORNING TO YOU, SIR -- WHEN
YOU'RE INSIDE A FRANLG DIOF THIS
MAGNITUDE, IT'S HARD TO IMAGINE
THAT YOU'RE EVER GOING TO BE
ABLE TO GET OUT OF IT.
IS THAT HOW YOU FELT WHEN
EVERYONE WAS MIRED IN THE
AFTERMATH OF THE OKLAHOMA CITY
BOMBING?
>> SOLEDAD, IT'S AN INSTANT
CATACLYSM FOR THE FAMILIES AND
FOR THE FIRST RESPONDERS, BUT
THE CLIMB OUT IS LONG, AND IT'S
SEARING AND IT'S VERY DIFFICULT.
TODAY, 17 YEARS AFTER THE
OKLAHOMA CITY BOMBING WITH
PRIVATE FUNDS WE ARE STILL
PUTTING CHILDREN THROUGH
COLLEGE, PROVIDING COUNSELING,
FIRST RESPONDERS, FIREFIGHTERS
AND POLICE OFFICERS AND EVEN
PROVIDING MEDICAL CARE FOR A
NUMBER OF THE BADLY INJURED.
SO THE ONE THING ABOUT NEWTOWN,
IT IS A COMMUNITY SO STITCHING
TOGETHER, HOLDING HANDS
TOGETHER, UNDERSTANDING YOUR
NEIGHBOR IS REALLY YOUR
NEIGHBOR, IF NOT A FAMILY
MEMBER.
THIS IS GOING TO BE A LONG TIME
CRAWLING OUT, SCRATCHING
YOURSELF OUT, BECAUSE IT'S GOING
TO BE SEARING.
WE'VE HAD SUICIDES JUST A LOT OF
AGONY AFTER THE OKLAHOMA CITY
BOMBING AND I'M AFRAID THAT THE
TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN IS NOT GOING
TO BE DECEMBER.
IT'S GOING TO TAKE A LONG TIME
TO RECOVER.
>> IT SOUNDS SO BRUTAL.
YOU MENTIONED THE FIRST
RESPONDERS, AND I REMEMBER
SEEING WHEN THE PRESIDENT CAME
TO THE INTERFAITH VIGIL, THE
FIRST RESPONDERS EVERYONE CAME
IN WALKED AND CHEERED AND PATTED
THEM ON THE BACK.
THEY'RE OFTEN FORGOTTEN IN THE
STORY, PEOPLE REMEMBER THEM AS
HEROES BUT WE DON'T THINK ABOUT
THEIR MENTAL HEALTH AND HOW
BRUTALLY DIFFICULT IT MUST HAVE
BEEN FOR THEM TO GO INSIDE THAT
SCHOOL AND SEE THE MASSACRE OF
SMALL CHILDREN, MANY OF THOSE
RESPONDERS, PARENTS THEMSELVES.
>> THAT'S THE POINT BECAUSE
RIGHT NOW I SAW THE UNIVERSITY
OF CONNECTICUT PUTTING TOGETHER
A SCHOLARSHIP FUND, SURELY THERE
ARE PRIVATE CHECKS ARRIVING,
PRIVATE TRANSMISSIONS OR
TRANSFERS OF MONEY.
I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT THAT A
COMMUNITY FOUNDATION OR PERHAPS
THE UNITED WAY INITIALLY PUT
TOGETHER A PLAN FOR HOW DO WE
ADDRESS THESE PROBLEMS.
SOME PEOPLE NEED LONG-TERM
COUNSELING.
THE FIRST RESPONDERS
PARTICULARLY PEOPLE NEED TO BE
SENSITIVE TO THOSE ABSOLUTELY
STUNNING, SEARING, SHOCKING,
UNFORGETTABLE MOMENTS OF THOSE
WONDERFUL LITTLE CHILDREN SO
PEOPLE NEED TO SIT AROUND THE
TABLE TOGETHER, WORK IT OUT, BUT
REALIZE THEY'RE GOING TO BE IN
THIS BUSINESS FOR A LONG TIME,
UNFORTUNATELY, TRAGICALLY THEY
HAVE TO WORK THROUGH IT FOR A
LONG TIME.
>> SO WHAT DO YOU THINK HAPPENS
NEXT?
ALL MORNING WE'VE BEEN REPORTING
ABOUT THE NEW FOCUS ON GUN
CONTROL, THERE IS A SUPPORT IF
YOU LOOK AT THE POLLS MUCH
HIGHER, 14 POINTS HIGHERS BEFORE
THIS MASSACRE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK HAPPENS IN
THAT CONVERSATION ON GUN
CONTROL?
WHAT CHANGE DO YOU THINK SHOULD
HAPPEN?
>> WELL I'M A HUNTER.
I'VE BEEN A HUNTER MY WHOLE
LIFE.
I HAD MY FIRST SHOTGUN WHEN I
WAS 11, MY FIRST JOB WAS IN A
SKEET FIELD.
I THINK THIS DEBATE, THIS
CONVERSATION NEEDS TO TAKE
PLACE.
SHOULD PEOPLE BE ABLE TO ACCESS
TO PURCHASE SEMIAUTOMATIC
WEAPONS WITH THESE CLIPS, THESE
MAGAZINES THAT PROVIDE FOR
BASICALLY UNLIMITED FIRE POWER?
THAT NEEDS TO BE DEBATED AND
DISCUSSED.
WE DID IT ONCE.
I THINK WE SHOULD DO IT AGAIN TO
BAN THOSE ASSAULT WEAPONS, BUT
ALSO YOU HAVE TO DISCUSS MENTAL
HEALTH, PRIVACY ISSUES, YOU HAVE
TO DISCUSS QUITE TRUTHFULLY THE
EASY DIVORCE PROCESS, EVEN WITH
CHILDREN, MARRIAGES ARE -- MORE
THAN 60% END IN DIVORCE.
VIDEO VIOLENCE, MOVIE VIOLENCE,
TELEVISION VIOLENCE, ALL OF THIS
SHOULD BE ON THE TABLE, ROUND
TABLE COMMUNITY RESOLUTION,
NATIONAL RESOLUTION SO WE CAN
MAKE SURE THIS IS AN ABERRATION
BUT AS A CHILD WE HAD CAP GUNS,
WE WENT HUNTING AFTER SCHOOL BUT
NONE OF US SLEIGHTERED O EE EEE
SLAUGHTERED OUR CLASSMATES.
THERE'S SOMETHING EVIL IN THE
HEARTS AND MINDS OF SOME PEOPLE.
THAT ALL NEEDS TO BE ADDRESSED.
>> THERE'S A STATE REP. IN YOUR
STATE, MARK McCULLOUGH, AND HE
WILL INTRODUCE A BILL WHICH
WOULD ALLOW CERTIFIED TEACHERS
AND PRINCIPALS TO CARRY GUNS IN
THE SCHOOL.
HERE'S WHAT HE WROTE, "WE CANNOT
CONTINUE TO BE SHACKLED BY
POLITICALLY RECORRECT,
REFLEXIVE, ANTI-GUN SENTIMENT IN
THE FACE OF THE OBVIOUS.
OUR SCHOOLS ARE SOFT TARGETS.
IT'S INCREDIBLY IRRESPONSIBLE TO
LEAVE OUR SCHOOLS UNDEFENDED TO
ALLOW MADMEN TO KILL DOZENS OF
INNOCENTS WHEN WE HAVE A VERY
SIMPLE AVAILABLE TO US TO
PREVENT IT AND BY THAT SOLUTION
HE MEANS ARMING SOME OF THE
TEACHERS AND THE PRINCIPALS.
DO YOU THINK THAT'S A GOOD IDEA
IN YOUR STATE, WHICH IS WHERE
HE'S PROPOSING IT IN.
>> SOLEDAD I WAS THE ARCHITECT
REALLY OF THE FIRST CONCEALED
CARRY LAW IN THE UNITED STATES
BUT WE REQUIRED A MENTAL HEALTH
HISTORY, CRIMINAL BACKGROUND
INVESTIGATION AND A 15-WEEK
COURSE BEFORE SOMEBODY COULD
HAVE A CONCEALED CARRY PERMIT.
THAT'S AN EXAMPLE WHERE PERHAPS
A FORMER LAW ENFORCEMENT PERSON,
EVEN A TEACHER WHO HAPPENS TO
HAVE A CONCEAL CARRY PERMIT IN
MY STATE COULD SATISFY THE NEEDS
OF SECURITY IN THAT SCHOOL.
I WOULD HOPE WE WOULD ATTACK THE
WHOLE UNIVERSE OF PROBLEMS AND
VIOLENT VIDEOS, VIOLENT MOVIES,
INSENSITIVITY AND DESENSITIVITY
TOWARD THE PRECIOUS LIFE RIGHTS
OF EVERY HUMAN BEING, THOSE ARE
THINGS THAT NEED TO BE DISCUSSED
AS WELL, WHETHER OKLAHOMA PASSES
THIS BILL OR NOT IS OKLAHOMA'S
BUSINESS BUT THE CONCEAL CARRY
LAW WAS PRUDENTLY HANDLED AND
OUR VIOLENT CRIME RATE HAS GONE
DOWN.
>> YOU KNOW WHAT'S INTERESTING
IN NEW YORK CITY NOT LONG AGO WE
HAD A DISGRUNTLED EMPLOYEE WHO
SHOT A CO-WORKER AND THEN IT
HAPPENED NOT VERY FAR FROM WHERE
I LIVE AND WHEN THE POLICE
OPENED FIRE IT TURNED OUT THAT
EIGHT OTHER PEOPLE WERE INJURED
IN THE CROSS-FIRE FRANKLY AND
SOME OF THE FRAGMENTS AND THINGS
LIKE THAT.
WHEN YOU TALK TO POLICE OFFICERS
THE IDEA OF HAVING PEOPLE ARMED
ESPECIALLY INSIDE OF A SCHOOL IS
MORE CONCERNING TO THEM THAN
FEELING THAT IT WOULD HELP THEM
IN WHAT THEY DO.
NOT EVERYBODY, BUT A LOT.
>> I THINK SOLEDAD, QUITE
TRUTHFULLY, IT WOULD DEPEND,
VERSUS URBAN, BIG CITY VERSUS
SMALL TOWNS.
IN THE CASE OF THE NEW YORK
INCIDENT, AS AN EX-FBI AGENT I
THOUGHT IT LOOKS TO ME THESE
GUYS WERE TRIGGER HAPPY.
YOU HAD A LOT OF SHOOTING GOING
ON WITH A LOT OF PEOPLE AROUND
WHICH WAS NOT HANDLED WELL.
>> THAT IS AN INTERESTING POINT
BECAUSE THEY'RE TRAINED, RIGHT?
TO BE A POLICE OFFICER IN THE
CITY OF NEW YORK REQUIRES SUCH
INCREDIBLE TRAINING ON WEAPONS I
GUESS I'D WORRY PEOPLE WHO ARE
NOT TRAINED LIKE THEY ARE YOU
KNOW AND WE SEE SO MANY PEOPLE
INJURED OUT OF THAT INCIDENT, I
GUESS I EXTRAPOLATE OUT OF THAT,
THAT'S VERY WORRISOME.
>> THAT'S WHY CONCEAL CARRY OR
OPEN CARRY LAW IN ANY STATE
NEEDS TO HAVE NOT ONLY MENTAL
HEALTH HISTORY AND CRIMINAL
BACKGROUND BUT ALSO EXTENSIVE
TRAINING TO AVOID THE SITUATION
YOU'RE REFERRING TO.
IF THAT PERSON IS A CONSTABLE
MAKE SURE HE OR SHE IS WELL
TRAINED.
>> LET ME ASK YOU A LAST FINAL
QUESTION, THE PEOPLE IN OKLAHOMA
CITY I KNOW DID NOT WANT TO BE
DEFINED PI A TRAGEDY AND WE
HEARD FROM PEOPLE THE SAME THING
IN NEWTOWN, NOBODY WANTS TO BE
DEFINED BY THE WORST THING THAT
EVER HAPPENS IN THEIR COMMUNITY.
DO YOU THINK THAT OKLAHOMA CITY
HAS AVOIDED THAT?
DO YOU THINK THAT'S POSSIBLE FOR
NEWTOWN?
>> WELL INITIALLY THAT WAS
EXAMINE KTLY HOW OKLAHOMA CITY
WAS DESCRIBED BUT THERE WAS A
RENAISSANCE MOMENT, OR
RENAISSANCE YEARS AGO.
THE FACT THAT OKLAHOMA CITY
SHOWED ITSELF TO BE SO CARING
SEEN SHARING, PUTTING TOGETHER
THESE FUNDS TO PUT EVERY CHILD,
170 CHILDREN LOST ONE PARENT.
EVERY CHILD WHO WANTED TO GO TO
COLLEGE WENT TO COLLEGE.
THE FACT THERE WAS NO LOOTING
AND OVER 300 BUILDINGS DAMAGED
OR DESTROYED, OKLAHOMA CITY WAS
PROUD OF THE WAY TO THE WAY THEY
RESPONDED TO THE EVIL TRAGEDY,
FROM THE OKLAHOMA CITY THUNDER
BASKETBALL GAME, THE NBA
FRANCHISE TO ALL SORTS OF
REDEVELOPMENT.
IT'S THE SENSE OF PRIDE.
I'M NOT SAYING ALWAYS GOOD
THINGS COME FROM BAD THINGS.
SOMETIMES GOOD FROM EVIL AND IN
OKLAHOMA CITY'S CASE THE
COMMUNITY FELT BETTER ABOUT
THEMSELVES.
THEY'LL NEVER BLING BACK THE
WONDERFUL PEOPLE WHO SHOULD NOT
HAVE BEEN INJURED OR KILLED.
>> MAYBE GOOD PEOPLE ALWAYS COME
TO THE SURFACE ON THAT.
FRANK KAETER, FORMER OKLAHOMA
GOVERNOR.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US.
>> GREAT TO SEE YOU.
>>> JOHN BERMAN HAS A LOOK AT
OTHER STORIES MAKING NEWS.
>> A DEVELOPING STORY IN
WASHINGTON, SIGNIFICANT MOVEMENT
TO AVERT THE FISCAL CLIFF.
PRESIDENT OBAMA PRESENTED A NEW
PROPOSAL TO HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER, UNDER THIS REVISED PLAN
TAX RATES WOULD GO UP ON INCOMES
HIGHER THAN $400,000.
PREVIOUSLY HE WANTED HIGHER
TAXES ON HOUSE HOLDS STARTING AT
$250,000.
THE OFFER OFFERS NEW SPENDING
CUTS WORTH $100 BILLION.
SPEAKER BAINER IS CALLING FOR
TAX HIKES ON PEOPLE MAKING $1
MILLION OR MORE, A CHANGE FOR
HIM, TOO.
TODAY HE MEETS WITH REPUBLICAN
HOUSE MEMBERS TO UPDATE THEM ON
NEGOTIATIONS, THAT COULD BE A
DIFFICULT MEETING FOR HIM.
I GO TO DANA BASH, SENIOR
CONGRESSIONAL COR SPENDENT.
YESTERDAY WE WERE TALKING ABOUT
THE MEETING WONDERING WHAT WENT
ON INSIDE.
WHAT SEEMED TO BE GOING ON WAS
PROGRESS.
>> THE WHITE HOUSE OFFERING OUT
A DEAL LATE OUT IN PART.
IT'S IMPORTANT TO NOTE WHERE THE
MOVEMENT HAS BEEN AND WHERE WE
ARE NOW, $1.2 TRILLION IN TAX
REVENUE TOWARD DEFICIT
REDUCTION, DOWN FROM WHAT THE
PRESIDENT OFFERED $1.6 TRILLION.
THE WHITE HOUSE IS NOW OFFERING
TO MOVE ON HIS POSITION ON TAX
RATES FOR THE WEALTHY FROM
INCOMES OF FAMILIES MAKING
TOO,000 TO $400,000.
THAT IS VERY SIGNIFICANT BECAUSE
DEMOCRATS I'VE TALKED TO ALL
ALONG SAID MAYBE THEY'D MOVE ON
THE PERCENTAGE OF INCREASES BUT
MAYBE NOT THE INCOMES.
SPENDING CUTS THE DEMOCRATS HAVE
MOVED UP AS WELL.
THE DEBT LIMIT, JOHN, SOMETHING
THAT REPUBLICANS HAVE BEEN DUG
IN ON SAYING THEY WANT TO KEEP
THIS POTENTIAL LEVERAGE OR
FEBRUARY WHEN THE U.S. IS GOING
TO BUMP UP AGAINST THIS DEBT
LIMIT AND THE DEMOCRATS HAVE
SAID NO, WE WANT TO TAKE THIS
OFF THE TABLE.
DOUGH WE DON'T WANT ANOTHER
NAUFR TWO MONTHS.
THERE IS GOING TO BE VERY
INTERESTING MEETING THAT STARTS
IN ABOUT 20 MINUTES, I'LL HEAD
OVER THERE AND SEE WHAT
REACTION, RESPONSE HOUSE
REPUBLICANS ARE GOING TO HAVE TO
THIS.
SO FAR THE SPEAKER HAS BEEN ABLE
TO KEEP HIS FOLKS IN LINE
BECAUSE THEY'VE BEEN AGGRAVATED
THE PRESIDENT'S NOT GIVEN.
WE'LL SEE IF HE STILL HAS ALL OF
HIS TLOOPZ BEHIND HIM.
>> THE $250,000 NUMBER FOR TAXES
HAS BEEN PART OF PRESIDENT OWE
PA MA'S RHETORIC SINCE HE
CAMPAIGNED IN IT007.
THE SPEAKER DOES GO INTO THAT
MEETING WITH REPUBLICANS WITH
MAYBE AN ARGUMENT THAT HE HAS
GOTTEN THE PRESIDENT TO MOVE.
>> HE SURE DOES BUT FOR
REPUBLICANS, FOR THEM TO
POLITICALLY BE ABLE TO SWALLOW
ANY DEAL THEY'VE GOT TO ARGUE TO
THEIR FOLKS BACK HOME THEY WERE
ABLE TO EXTRACT MORE ON SPENDING
CUTS FROM THE PRESIDENT.
IT LOOKS LIKE $930 BILLION IN
SPENDING CUTS AND A DISCREPANCY
OVER WHAT THE NUMBERS REALLY ARE
SO THAT'S THE SQUABBLE OVER THE
NEXT 24 HOURS.
HOPEFULLY LESS.
>> DEY TA BASH, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
>>> OTHER STORIES, DIRECTOR FOR
NATIONAL INTELLIGENCE FOR THE
UNITED STATES IS STAYING ON THE
JOB.
THE PRESIDENT ASKED JAMES
CLAPPER TO STAY ON THE JOB.
HE'S TAKEN A LOT OF HEAT AND
CRITICISM FOR THE RESPONSE TO
THE SEPTEMBER 11th ATTACK ON THE
U.S. MISSION IN BENGHAZI.
>>> DOCTORS EXPECT PRESIDENT
GEORGE H.W. BUSH TO BE HOME FROM
ILLNESS.
AT 88 YEARS OLD HE'S THE LOADEST
LIVING FORMER PRESIDENT.
MARTIN SCORSESE WILL COVER A
FILM ON BILL CLINTON.
HE'S COOPERATING.
I'M SURE HE'S LOVING EVERY BIT
OF THAT.
BACK TO SOLEDAD IN NEWTOWN.
>> IF MARTY SCORSESE WANTS TO DO
A FILM ON YOU, HE DOES IT.
>>> AHEAD THIS MORNING WE'LL
TALK TO PASTY T.D. JAKES ABOUT
HOW NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT MIGHT BE
ABLE TO HEAL.
THAT'S COMING UP NEXT.
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>>> A TRAGEDY OF THE MAGNITUDE
OF THE DEADLY SHOOTINGS AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, CAN SHAKE
THE FAITH OF THE FIRMEST
BELIEVER.
T.D. JAKES HAS A CONGREGATION OF
30,000 MEMBERS.
>> THANK YOU.
>> I WAS READING THE EULOGY THAT
THE MOTHER OF 6-YEAR-OLD NOAH
POZNER WROTE AND SHE DELIVERED
IT AT HIS FUNERAL YESTERDAY AND
IT JUST BROKE MY HEART AND I
THINK HOW DO YOU COUNSEL PARENTS
WHO HAVE TO DELIVER EULOGIES FOR
A 6-YEAR-OLD OR 7-YEAR-OLD?
WHAT WORDS DO YOU POSSIBLY USE?
>> YOU DON'T WANT TO THINK WE
HAVE TO REMEMBER ABOUT GREECE
THEY ARE NOT A MONOLITHING
SOCIETY.
FOR SOME PEOPLE THAT WOULD BE
TOTALLY IMPOSSIBLE TO UTTER A
WORD OR A SOUND.
FOR OTHER PEOPLE IT'S CATHARTIC
TO OPEN UP AND EXPRESS THEIR
LOVE AND DEVOTION AND TO HAVE
THE FINAL WORDS OVER SOMEONE
THEY LOVE.
I TRY VERY MUCH AS A PASTOR NOT
TO AMONG THEIR RELATIONSHIPS AND
EMOTIONS AND HOW THEY USE TO
COMMEMORATE THE PERSON THEY
LEAPLY WILL HAVE.
>> AS A REPORTER I LIKE TO GET
AS MANY INFORMATION AS YOU CAN.
I WANT TO KNOW EVERY DETAIL
ABOUT EVERYTHING AND THAT'S A
WAY OF PROCESSING IT, MANAGING
IT.
PEOPLE MUST ASK YOU QUESTIONS
YOU CANNOT ANSWER.
AND THEY SAY WHERE WAS GOD WHEN
THIS HAPPENED?
>> IT'S PRECISELY AS YOU IS
ASAID I'VE TRIED TO AVOID
ANSWERS GOESABLE TEMPORARY.
THERE ARE SOME THINGS THAT ARE
HANDEDS NOW LIFE THAT WE DO NOT
KNOW OR UNDERSTAND.
THESE AREAS, AMBIGUOUS AREAS
WHERE WE DON'T HAVE A DEFICIT
ANSWER IT'S BETTER NOT TO GIVE
ANY ANSWER AT ALL THAN TO GIVE
ONE INAPPROPRIATE.
THAT'S WHY WE HAVE FAITH FOR
THOSE THINGS WE CANNOT EXPLAIN
AND POINT TO DIRECTLY, WE HAVE
TO FRTRUST GOD AND LEAN ON HIM
GET THROUGH THE SUFFICIENT TIMES
IN LIFE.
>> THERE WAS A LITTLE GIRL
EMILIES WHO FATHER CAME OUT TO
REPORTERS.
HE SAID I'M NOT ANGRY.
WE'VE BIN AND TALKED ABOUT
FORGIVENESS IT'S FOR YOURSELF
NOT FOR THE OTHER PERSON IN A
LOT OF WAYS.
DO YOU THINK PEOPLE ARE EVER
GOING TO BE ABLE TO GET TO THAT
NOT JUST HERE IN THIS MASSACRE?
I DON'T SEE IT HAPPENING
HONESTLY.
>> WELL I THINK DIFFERENT PEOPLE
AGAIN RESPOND DIFFERENTLY BUT
ONE OF THE THINGS WE HAVE TO
KEEP IN NIND IS THAT WE DON'T
KNOW THAT MUCH ABOUT THE TRAITOR
YET.
AS YOU UNFOENL THAT MYSTERY THAT
ARE NOT ON MEDICATION BUT THEY
HAVE PROBLEMS IN THEIR LIVES,
THAT I EMOTIONAL CAPACITIES AND
REASONINGS, SOMETIMES UNDER
EX-TEN SITUATING SERVICES PEOPLE
ARE ABLE TO FORGIVE AND OTHERS
NOT SO READILY.
TODAY IS NOT THE DAY TO EMBARK
UPON A HUGE MISSION.
TODAY IS THE WAY TO HONOR THE
VICTIMS SLAIN TO PROCESS, TO
COMMEMORATE THEM, TO TAKE OUT
PICTURES TO HUG, HOLD HANDS,
BRING AROUND THE PEOPLE YOU FEEL
SECURE WITH AND REAFFIRM YOUR
CIRCLE OF LOVE BECAUSE IF WE DO
THAT AS A SOCIETY FROM THAT
PLACE OF EMOTIONAL STABILITY,
THEN WE CAN EMBARK ON THEARD USE
TASK OF SORTING OUT HOW WE
REALLY FEEL ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
AND THEN PLANNING A NEW WHAT I
CALL A NEW NORMAL BECAUSE THE
ONLY NORMAL IS GONE.
YOU WILL NEVER BE ABLE TO GET
THAT BACK AGAIN AND IT'S VERY
IMPORTANT YOU REDEKIND THE NEW
NORMAL, NEW TRADITIONS IN THE
FAMILY, NO WAYS OF EXPRESSING
THE FAMILY AND THAT IS A HUGE
TASK YOU SPEND MANY, MANY YEARS
TRYING TO DO.
>> PASTOR WE'LL ASK TO YOU STICK
AROUND THROUGH THIS COMMERCIAL
BREAK SO WE CAN HAVE MORE
CONVERSATION WITH YOU ABOUT THIS
STRAIGHT AHEAD.
BACK IN A MOMENT.
>> THANK YOU.
it really 100 cal?
Let me put you on webcan...
...lean roasted chicken...
and a creamy broth
Mmm
I can still see you.
to the number 1 club
in the world.
The potential of
Manchester United unlocked.
NYSE Euronext.
Unlocking the world's potential.
>>> BISHOP JAKES, I HAVE TIME
FOR ONE LAST QUESTION AS WE TALK
ABOUT NEWTOWN, REMEMBERING.
YOUR CHURCH DOES A LOT OF
OUTREACH INTO THE COMMUNITY AND
SOMETIMES I THINK AS AMERICANS
WE'RE CONFLICTED ABOUT MENTAL
HEALTH.
WE THINK PEOPLE DEFINITELY
SHOULD BE GETTING TREATMENT.
WE DON'T NECESSARILY VOTE TO PAY
FOR IT.
WE TURN AWAY FROM PEOPLE I THINK
WHO OFTEN HAVE MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES BECAUSE WE DON'T WANT TO
GET IN PEOPLE'S BUSINESS.
WHAT SHOULD WE BE DOING FOR NOT
IN THIS CASE, WE DON'T KNOW
ENOUGH ABOUT THE SHOOTER BUT IN
GENERAL WHAT WOULD YOU ADVISE
PEOPLE TO BE DOING FOR THEIR
FELLOW BROTHERS AND SISTERS.
>> I'M SO GLAD YOU ASKED ME THE
QUESTION.
I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT WE PRESS
ON CONGRESS TO PROVIDE RESOURCES
SO PEOPLE WHO NEED MENTAL HEALTH
CAN GET THE APPROPRIATE
TREATMENT THAT WE NEED.
I CAUTION PEOPLE THAT YOU DON'T
HAVE TO HAVE A FRE EXISTING
MENTAL CONDITION TO IMPLODE
EMOTIONALLY THROUGH STRESS.
WE HAVE TO AGE OLD BIBLICAL
QUESTION AM I MY BROTHER'S
KEEPER, THE ANSWER IS YES.
WE HAVE TO BE AWARE WHO WE WORK
WITH, THE PEOPLE ACROSS THE
FENCE IN OUR NEIGHBORHOOD, SEE
HOW THEY ARE COPING PARTICULARLY
WHEN THERE'S CHECK CRISIS, YOU
DON'T HAVE TO HAVE A HISTORY OF
EMOTIONAL DISORDER.
WE HAVE TO ENCOURAGE THEM TO GET
THE HELP.
>> BISHOP T.D. JAKES NICE TO
TALK TO YOU.
APPRECIATE IT.
>> ALWAYS.
>>> CNN'S COVERAGE LIVE FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, CONTINUES
RIGHT AFTER THIS.
NATURE VALLS
PACK THE BIG TASTE
OF GRANOLA AND DARK CHOCOLATE
INTO ONE PERFECT SQUARE,
UNDER 100 CALORIES.
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA THINS.
WHY THEY HAVE A
RAISE YOUR RATE CD..
TONIGHT OUR GUEST,
THOMAS SARGENT.
NOBEL LAUREATE
IN ECONOMICS,
AND ONE OF THE MOST CITED
ECONOMISTS IN THE WORLD.
PROFESSOR SARGENT,
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT CD RATES WILL
BE IN TWO YEARS?
NO.
IF HE CAN'T, NO ONE CAN.
THAT'S WHY ALLY HAS
A RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
ALLY BANK.
YOUR MONEY NEEDS AN ALLY.