>>> HELLO, EVERYONE.
WE ARE FOLLOWING BREAKING NEWS
IN NEWTOWN, A TOWN BETWEEN
STANFORD AND HARTFORD.
WE'RE FOLLOWING REPORTS THAT
THERE HAS BEEN A SHOOTING AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL NAMED SANDY
HOOK.
ONE PHOTOGRAPH TO SHARE WITH YOU
AS CREWS RUSH TO THE SCENE.
LET ME BRING IN MY COLLEAGUE
JASON CARROLL WHO HAS BEEN
WORKING HIS SOURCES.
WHAT DO WE KNOW?
>> DISTURBING STORY.
THE SHOOTING HAPPENING AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL ON
DICKERSON DRIVE.
THIS IS COMING TO US FROM ONE OF
OUR AFFILIATES.
POLICE ARE REPORTING A NUMBER OF
INJURIES.
THE NATURE OF THE INJURIES AT
THIS POINT ARE UNCLEAR.
WE'RE GOING TO BE CHECKING THAT
THROUGHOUT THE MORNING.
STATE POLICE SOURCES SAY THAT
ONE PERSON IS DEAD.
EARLIER REPORTS OF A SECOND
SHOOTER.
THAT HAS NOT BEEN CONFIRMED AT
THIS POINT.
A FEW MORE REPORTS, APPARENTLY
THE SHOOTING WAS REPORTED
SHORTLY AFTER 9:40 A.M. THIS
MORNING.
POLICE REPORTED THAT A SHOOTER
WAS IN THE -- APPARENTLY IN THE
MAIN OFFICE.
>> WHICH IS HARD TO TELL WITH
THIS IMAGE THAT WE'RE LOOKING AT
BECAUSE THAT'S SORT OF
BIRD'S-EYE VIEW OF THE SCHOOL
LAYOUT DOESN'T SHOW WHERE THAT
IS.
WE SHOULD MENTION THAT ONE OF
THE TV STATIONS THAT HAS BEEN
REPORTING ON THIS WAS TOLD BY A
WITNESS THAT SHE SAW TWO
CHILDREN, ONE WITH A BLOODY FACE
AND THE OTHER WITH WHAT APPEARED
TO BE A HAND INJURY.
AGAIN, THAT COMING IN TO NEWS 8,
ONE OF THE LOCAL STATIONS IN THE
AREA.
>> THAT FALLS IN STEP WITH ONE
OF THE REPORTS THAT WE'RE
HEARING, THAT A PERSON IN ONE OF
THE ROOMS HAS, QUOTE, NUMEROUS
GUNSHOT WOUNDS.
IT'S DIFFICULT TO TELL FROM SOME
OF THESE IMAGES THAT WE'RE
GETTING INTO OUR NEWSROOM WHERE
ALL OF THIS IS HAPPENING AT THE
SCHOOL.
>> IS THERE ANY REPORTING AT
ALL, JASON?
THIS JUST BROKE WITHIN THE LAST
FEW MOMENTS BUT ANY REPORTS THAT
THE SHOOTER MAY HAVE BEEN A
STUDENT OR PERHAPS WAS THIS
STAFF-RELATED?
WHENEVER YOU HEAR ABOUT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, THE LAST
THING THAT YOU CAN IMAGINE IS A
CHILD THAT MIGHT HAVE BROUGHT A
GUN TO SCHOOL AND I DO HAVE
SOMETHING FROM THE WEBSITE THAT
SAYS THIS IS A SCHOOL THAT
BEGINS IN KINDERGARTEN AND ONLY
GOES UP TO FOURTH GRADE.
THESE ARE VERY YOUNG CHILDREN.
>> ONE OF OUR PRODUCERS IS
TELLING US THAT SHE SPOKE TO A
FATHER FROM THE DISTRICT WHO
REPORTED THAT ONE CHILD WAS IN
FACT TAKEN AWAY AND THAT CHILD
WAS SERIOUSLY INJURED, QUOTE,
SERIOUSLY INJURED.
THAT'S ONE CHILD TAKEN AWAY WITH
SERIOUS INJURIES.
>> BY AMBULANCE?
>> BY AMBULANCE.
AND THAT FALLS IN STEP WITH WHAT
WE HEARD ABOUT NUMEROUS GUNSHOT
WOUNDS.
ALSO, WE'RE BEING TOLD THAT
GROUPS OF STUDENTS, SOME OF THEM
CRYING, SOME OF THEM HOLDING
HANDS WERE ESCORTED AWAY FROM
THE SCHOOL BY THEIR TEACHERS.
SOME WERE IN SCHOOL STILL AS OF
10:30 A.M.
>> THERE IS SOMETHING ON THE
WEBSITE AND IT'S UNKNOWN IF IT
WAS POSTED BEFORE OR AFTER THE
SHOOTING BUT IT DOES SAY THAT
AFTERNOON KINDERGARTEN IS
CANCELED AND THERE WILL BE NO
MIDDAY BUS RUNS.
AGAIN, NO OTHER INCLINATION.
POLICE WERE CALLED AND HAVE
RESPONDED BECAUSE OF WHAT THEY
WERE TOLD WAS A SHOOTING.
>> AND I'M SURE WE'LL BE GETTING
MORE DETAILS COMING IN.
BECAUSE, AGAIN, DOZENS OF STATE
TROOPERS ARE ASSISTING LOCAL
POLICE.
HEAVILY ARMED POLICE ARE
GATHERED FROM THE SCHOOL AND A
NUMBER OF STRETCHERS HAVE BEEN
SET UP AS A PRECAUTION.
A STAGING AREA ALSO SET UP FOR
STUDENT AND THEIR PARENTS NEAR
THEIR SCHOOL, AS YOU CAN
IMAGINE.
A NUMBER OF PARENTS SITTING AT
HOME WATCHING THIS ARE GOING TO
BE WATCHING THIS WANTING TO --
ARE GOING TO BE WANTING TO KNOW
WHERE THEY SHOULD GO AND WHAT
THEY SHOULD DO TO MAKE SURE THAT
THEIR KIDS ARE SAFE.
>> WHAT'S REMARKABLE ABOUT THIS
AS WELL IS THAT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY IN NEWTOWN, KU
CONNECTICUT IS MIDWAY
NORTH-SOUTH BETWEEN STANFORD
WHICH WOULD BE IN THE BOTTOM
LEFT HAND CORNER.
>> VERY CLOSE TO DANBURY?
>> YES.
BUT A LONG WAY AWAY FROM THE
COAST WHICH IS WHAT MOST PEOPLE
ARE FAMILIAR WITH AND THE METRO
TRAIN LINES, ET CETERA.
AND ALSO VERY DIFFICULT FOR
REPORTERS TO GET THERE AND
OTHERS AS WELL.
LOU PALUMBO IS A RETIRED NASSAU
COUNTY POLICE OFFICER.
I KNOW YOU'VE HAD THESE CALLS IN
YOUR PAST.
WHAT IS THE PROTOCOL?
WHAT HAPPENS IMMEDIATELY WHEN A
CALL COMES IN TO AUTHORITIES
THAT IT IS AN ELEMENTARY SQUOCH
WHEN THEY ARE DEALING WITH A
POSSIBLE SHOOTER.
>> ASHLEIGH?
>> HI, LOU.
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
>> I CAN BARELY HEAR YOU.
>> I'M TRYING TO GET A READ FROM
YOU, WITH YOUR PAST EXPERIENCE,
WHEN A CALL COMES IN THAT THERE
MAY BE A SHOOTER AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, IS THERE A
PROTOCOL?
CAN YOU WALK ME THROUGH WHAT
THESE RESPONDING OFFICERS ARE
DOING RIGHT NOW?
>> I CAN TELL YOU THIS,
ESPECIALLY WITH INCIDENTS
INVOLVING CHILDREN, WHETHER THEY
ARE STRUCK BY AUTOS OR INCIDENTS
OF THE SCHOOLS, YOU JUST CAN'T
GET THERE FAST ENOUGH.
WE REALLY DON'T EXPECT TO HAVE
INCIDENTS OF THIS TYPE
HAPPENING.
>> LOU, ON THE PHONE RIGHT NOW
IS MIKE BRANCHWELL.
I'M BEING TOLD THAT YOU HAVE
FOUR CHILDREN IN THIS SCHOOL?
MR. BRANCHWELL, CAN YOU HEAR ME?
>> WE JUST LOST THAT CONNECTION.
WE'LL TRY TO RE-ESTABLISH OUR
CONNECTION WITH MIKE BRANCH
WELL.
IN THE MEANTIME, IF YOU'RE JUST
JOINING US, THERE IS SO LITTLE,
UNFORTUNATELY, TO REPORT ON THIS
WHICH IS WORRY SOME IN ITSELF
THAT THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IS ON LOCKDOWN.
I THINK WE HAVE MIKE BRANCHWELL
BACK ON THE PHONE.
MIKE, CAN YOU HEAR ME?
>> YES.
>> I THINK YOU HAVE FOUR
CHILDREN.
ARE THEY ALL IN THIS SCHOOL?
>> WE HAVE TWO THAT HAVE
GRADUATED.
NO ONE HAS BEEN THROUGH THE
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
>> BUT IS THERE SOMETHING THAT
YOU CAN ADD TO THIS?
IS THIS YOUR COMMUNITY?
IS THIS YOUR NEIGHBORHOOD?
>> YES, IT'S OUR COMMUNITY AND
NEIGHBORHOOD AND OUR CHILDREN
HAVE FRIENDS THAT GO TO THAT
SCHOOL.
WE HAVE A DAUGHTER WHO IS IN AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL BUT NOT THAT
ACTUAL SCHOOL.
>> SO WHAT DO YOU KNOW ABOUT
WHAT IS HAPPENING?
THERE SEEMS TO BE A REAL VACUUM
OF INFORMATION.
HAVE YOU SEEN ANYTHING?
HAVE YOU SEEN RESPONDERS GOING
BY IN WHAT DO YOU KNOW?
>> WE KNOW THAT THERE ARE A
NUMBER OF RESPONDERS AT THE
SCHOOL.
THE SCHOOL HAS A VERY GOOD
SYSTEM OF COMMUNICATING TO
PARENT.
WE'VE GOT E-MAILS AND TEXTS AND
UPDATED INFORMATION.
THERE WAS AN INCIDENT.
THE SCHOOL IS ON LOCKDOWN.
WE HAVE A FRESHMAN AT THE HIGH
SCHOOL WHO HAS BEEN TEXTING US.
HE'S IN LOCKDOWN IN THE SILENCE
LAB AT THE MOMENT.
BUT --
>> SO YOUR CHILD, THE FRESHMAN
IN HIGH SCHOOL, HAS BEEN ABLE TO
TEXT YOU THAT THERE IS A
LOCKDOWN AT THAT SCHOOL?
BECAUSE WE HAVE HEARD THAT THE
WHOLE DISTRICT IS IN LOCKDOWN.
THAT WOULD SQUARE WITH WHAT WE
ARE BEING TOLD.
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
THEY DO PRACTICE THIS.
WE HAVE BEEN HERE SINCE 2005 AND
THE SCHOOLS ARE VERY FORWARD
THINKING AND VERY PROACTIVE.
AND SADLY IN THIS TYPE OF
SITUATION.
SO THE KIDS KNOW WHAT TO EXPECT
AND WHAT TO DO.
WE DO CURRENTLY HAVE A FRESHMAN
IN LOCKDOWN.
>> AND THAT FRESHMAN, IS THAT A
SON OR DAUGHTER?
>> IT'S OUR SON.
>> AND HAS YOUR SON BEEN ABLE TO
TEXT YOU ANY OTHER KINDS OF
INFORMATION THAT HE MAY BE
HEARING WITHIN THE SCHOOL
ITSELF, NOT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL BUT THE HIGH SCHOOL?
>> I THINK THAT THEY ARE ALL
USING PRECAUTIONS AND THE
TEACHERS HAVE GOT THE SITUATION
UNDER CONTROL.
HE KNOWS.
>> CAN YOU TELL ME A LITTLE BIT
ABOUT NEWTOWN, THE SIZE AND
PROXIMITY TO WHAT OTHER PEOPLE
IN THE UNITED STATES MIGHT GLEAM
FROM IT, IF YOU CAN GIVE US A
DESCRIPTION OF YOUR TOWN?
>> IT'S A SMALL TOWN, VERY LARGE
SQUARE MILES BUT LOW POPULATION.
IT'S A VERY QUIET TOWN.
GREAT SENSE OF COMMUNITY AND THE
SCHOOLS ARE VERY HIGHLY RATED.
>> ALL RIGHT.
I WANT TO JUST ASK YOU TO STAND
BY, IF YOU WILL.
MY COLLEAGUE, JASON CARROLL, HAS
BEEN COLLECTING MORE
INFORMATION.
>> I THINK WE HAVE MORE
INFORMATION THAT MAY BE
IMPORTANT FOR PARENT.
WE'RE TOLD THAT THERE IS A
STAGING AREA SORT OF I AM PROM
TEA BEING SET UP AT VILLAGE
RESTAURANT AND PIZZA.
APPARENTLY THE PARKING LOT
THERE.
THE SCHOOL IS JUST OVER THE HILL
FROM THAT LOCATION, JUST ABOUT A
FIVE-MINUTE WALK AWAY FROM THERE
AND APPARENTLY A NUMBER OF
PARENTS ARE GATHERED THERE
TRYING TO GET INFORMATION.
THAT'S BEING SET UP AS SOME SORT
OF INFORMAL STAGING AREA FOR
PARENTS TRYING TO GET
INFORMATION ABOUT THEIR CHILDREN
ABOUT WHAT IS HAPPENING THERE
AND THEY ARE DOING WHAT THEY CAN
TO HELP THIS TSHOOTING.
>> ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, JUST TO
RECAP YOU, AN ELEMENT REE SCHOOL
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, IN THE
SOUTHWESTERN PART.
THIS IS THE AERIAL VIEW OF WHAT
THE SCHOOL LOOKS LIKE AND YOU
CAN TELL HOW BIG THE LAYOUT OF
THIS SCHOOL IS.
BUT THE HARTFORD IS SAYING THAT
ONE PERSON HAD NUMEROUS WOUNDS.
WE'RE NOT BEING GIVEN ANY
INFORMATION AT THIS POINT.
IF THERE ARE OTHER INJURIES OR
WHERE THOSE CHILDREN ARE IN THAT
SCHOOL RIGHT NOW.
WE'RE GOING TO SQUEEZE IN A
QUICK BREAK, GATHER MORE
INFORMATION, AND BE RIGHT BACK
AFTER THIS.
[ sniffs ] I HAVE A COLD.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
Bye!
Santa, we made a video for
your trip!
Yeah, you can watch it on your
sleigh!
OK!
Here you go.
Aw, thanks elves.
I also made you a video.
You are so sweet.
But you probably shouldn't watch
it on the sleigh.
Say goodbye to Santa boys!
Bye!
Good bye Santa!
Share videos instantly
with S Beam on the
Galaxy S3 and Note 2.
Available at Best Buy and
Best Buy mobile stores.
>>> TO UPDATE YOU ON WHAT WE'VE
BEEN COVERING, COURTESY OF OUR
AFFILIATE, THIS IS IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
IT'S A TOWN MIDDAY BETWEEN
STANFORD AND HARTFORD IN
SOUTHWESTERN CONNECTICUT.
REPORTS CAME IN EARLY THIS
MORNING OF A SHOOTING AND THE
RESPONSE WAS QUICK AND FURIOUS.
YOU CAN SEE NOW FROM THE AERIAL
SHOTS SOME OF THE OFFICERS, ONE
OF THEM WITH A CANINE UNIT ON
THE SCENE.
WE ALSO HAVE REPORTS FROM ONE OF
THE AFFILIATES THERE THAT A
WITNESS SAW A HAND INJURY AND A
BLOODY FACE.
WE CAN TELL YOU AS WELL THAT
PARENTS HAVE BEEN ADVISED TO
STAY AT HOME.
PARENTS HAVE BEEN TOLD TO STAY
AT HOME.
THESE PICTURES JUST SHOT MOMENTS
AGO IN WHAT APPEARS TO BE THE
PARKING LOT AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
YOU CAN SEE A NUMBER OF POLICE
AND A CHILD BEING TAKEN AWAY BY
AMBULANCE AND PARENTS YOU CAN
SEE IN THAT SHOT WALKING THROUGH
AND CARRYING THEIR CHILDREN,
ANOTHER ONE HOLDING ON TO KIDS,
TOO.
WE ALSO HEARD THAT SOME OF THE
CHILDREN, IF NOT ALL OF THEM,
HAVE BEEN EVACUATED TO A NEARBY
FIREHOUSE.
THE GROUND PICTURES SHOWING
THINGS FAIRLY CALM BUT CERTAINLY
A STRONG POLICE PRESENCE AND
WHAT THAT CANINE UNIT IS DOING.
I'M NOT CLEAR.
THEY SEEM TO BE INTERESTED IN
THAT CONTAINER.
AT LEAST THERE'S A SIGNAL COMING
FROM THE DOG SITTING AND THEN
SPENDING SOME EXTRA TIME AT THAT
CON TEARER.
JASON CARROLL IS ALSO MONITORING
SOME OF THE DETAILS COMING IN.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW?
>> WE ARE GETTING DETAILS COMING
IN FROM OUR AFFILIATES.
OBVIOUSLY POLICE ARE REPORTING A
NUMBER OF INJURIES.
THERE IS A REPORT THAT STATE
POLICE SOURCES SAY THAT ONE
SHOOTER MAY, IN FACT, BE DEAD,
ASHLEIGH.
THE SHOOTING WAS REPORTED AT
9:40 A.M.
POLICE REPORTED IT THAT A
SHOOTER WAS IN THE MAIN OFFICE
OF THE SCHOOL.
A FATHER HAD CALLED IN TO OUR
DESK HERE IN NEW YORK A FEW
MOMENTS AGO.
>> I HAVE A SAD REPORT.
I HAVE TO BREAK IN.
A SAD REPORTING COMING AS WELL.
THEY ARE NOW CONFIRMING ONE
CHILD DEAD AS A RESULT OF THIS
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
HARTFORD CURRENT REPORTING ONE
CHILD DEAD AS A RESULT OF THIS
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
WE DON'T KNOW ANYTHING ELSE
ABOUT ADDITIONAL SHOOTING
VICTIMS.
AGAIN, THESE PICTURES ARE JUST
COMING IN FROM NEWS 12 NEW
JERSEY.
THIS IS AN EMPTY STRETCHER BEING
WHEELED TOWARDS THE SCHOOL AT
THIS POINT.
YOU CAN SEE SOME OF THE CHILDREN
WITH I CAN ONLY MANUAL SOME
PARENT THAT HAVE BEEN RESPONDING
AS WELL AS FIRST RESPONDERS.
PARENTS HAVE BEEN ASKED TO STAY
HOME, ALTHOUGH YOU CAN IMAGINE
WHAT IT WOULD BE LIKE IF YOU HAD
CHILDREN IN THAT SCHOOL.
THE LAST THING YOU WOULD THINK
OF TO DO IS TO STAY HOME.
POLICE ARE BRANCHING OUT TO THE
SURROUNDING AREA.
THE SCHOOL IS SORT OF A SQUARE
FORMATION.
IT'S A LARGE CAMPUS FOR AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
YOU CAN SEE THAT THEY ARE
HEADING OUT INTO THE BRUSH
LOOKING FOR EVIDENCE.
I WANT TO WELCOME OUR VIEWERS
FROM AROUND THE WORLD.
A REPORTING OF A SCHOOL SHOOTING
IN CONNECTICUT AT AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL CALLED SANDY HOOK IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
REPORTS THAT EARLY THIS MORNING
PROBABLY JUST AFTER SCHOOL HAD
GOTTEN UNDER WAY, REPORTS OF A
SHOOTING IN WHICH OFFICERS
RESPONDED TO VERY QUICKLY.
VERY LITTLE INFORMATION RIGHT
NOW.
THE HARTFORD CURRENT, A NOTABLE
NEWSPAPER IN CONNECTICUT, IS
REPORTING THAT THERE IS ONE
CHILD CONFIRMED DEAD IN THIS
VERY TERRIBLE SHOOTING
SITUATION.
WE HAD HEARD REPORTS THAT THERE
COULD HAVE BEEN MULTIPLE
SHOOTERS.
THAT IS UNCONFIRMED AT THIS
POINT.
BUT PARENT OBVIOUSLY NERVOUS
ABOUT THESE REPORTS.
SOME OF THEM RESPONDING ON THE
SITE.
YOU CAN SEE THESE PICTURES
COMING INTO US.
THE ROADS, WE'RE ALSO TOLD, HAVE
BEEN SHUT DOWN AND TRAFFIC HAS
BEEN BOTTLENECKED IN THIS AREA.
THIS IS NOT FAR FROM DANBURY.
GEOGRAPHICALLY SPEAKING,
PROBABLY ABOUT AN HOUR, 40
MINUTE DRIVE FROM NEW YORK CITY
IF YOU'RE HEADING UP THE COAST
AND THEN INLAND SOMEWHAT,
BETWEEN STANFORD DOWN IN THE
SOUTHWEST CORNER AND HARTFORD AS
YOU CAN SEE IN THE CORNER, THE
CAPITAL OF THE STATE.
JASON?
>> AS WE SAW THE PICTURE OF THE
MAN WITH THE YOUNG BOY, YOU CAN
IMAGINE HOW TRAUMATIZING THIS
MUST BE FOR THE CHILDREN.
THIS IS AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THEY WERE CRYING AND HOLDING
HANDS.
>> THEY HAVE THESE PROTOCOLS
WHEN ANYTHING LIKE THIS -- OF
THIS MAGNITUDE, THERE ARE
PROTOCOLS TO LOCK DOWN AND
BARRICADE YOURSELF, FIND SAFE
POSITIONS UNTIL AN ALL CLEAR IS
INDICATED TO GET THE KIDS OUT OF
SCHOOL.
>> OBVIOUSLY AS THE HOURS MOVE
ON, WE'RE GOING TO BE TRYING TO
GET INFORMATION ABOUT THE MOTIVE
OF THE SITUATION.
>> OR WHO?
IS IT ANNED A DULT.
>> IT'S ALWAYS DIFFICULT TO
FIGURE OUT WHY THESE KINDS OF
THINGS HAPPEN.
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
WILL BE HOLDING A NEWS
CONFERENCE TWO HOURS FROM NOW.
PERHAPS AT THAT POINT MORE
INFORMATION WILL BE GIVEN ABOUT
THE MOTIVE BEHIND THE SHOOTING.
IT'S ALL DIFFICULT TO UNDERSTAND
WHY THESE THING HAPPEN.
>> I WANT TO DIP INTO OUR
AFFILIATE COVERAGE.
BRIDGEPORT HOSPITAL, WHICH IS
ABOUT A HALF HOUR DRIVE BY
GUESSTIMATION FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, THE TRAUMA TEAM
BEGAN GETTING CALLS THIS
MORNING.
LET'S LISTEN TO THE LOCAL
COVERAGE IN THIS HOUR.
THE HOSPITAL TRAUMA TEAM BEGAN
GETTING CALLS.
LET'S LISTEN TO THE LOCAL
COVERAGE.
>> I KNOW PARENT ARE JUST SO
HUNGRY FOR INFORMATION.
WE ARE STAYING ON AIR AND AS
SOON AS WE HAVE CREWS ON THE
SCENE, MANY HAVE BEEN ARRIVING.
WE ARE STAYING ON AIR.
AS SOON AS WE HAVE CREWS ON THE
SCENE, MANY HAVE BEEN ARRIVING.
WE ARE STAYING ON AIR AND AS
SOON AS WE HAVE CREWS ON THE
SCENE, MANY ARE JUST ARRIVING.
>> IF WE CAN CONTINUE TO GET
THAT SIGNAL FROM WFSB, I WANT TO
LET YOU KNOW THAT AS WE WERE
GOING TO THE LOCAL COVERAGE, I
TOLD YOU THAT BRIDGEPORT
HOSPITAL, THEIR TRAUMA TEAM WAS
GETTING READY AFTER GETTING
CALLS AT 9:40 A.M. LOCAL TIME.
MANY SCHOOLS IN CONNECTICUT,
ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS, ANYWAY.
IT'S OFTEN AN 8:00 A.M. START.
I HAVE TWO CHILDREN IN A
CONNECTICUT ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
AND THAT IS AN 8:00 A.M. START.
THIS ENTIRE DISTRICT, THOUGH, IS
ON LOCKDOWN.
WE ALSO KNOW THAT DANBURY
HOSPITAL, NOT FAR AWAY, HAS NOW
BEEN REPORTEDLY -- THREE PEOPLE
AS A RESULT OF THIS SHOOTING.
I HAVE NO IDEA WHAT THE EXTENT
OF THE INJURIES MAY BE.
DANBURY HOSPITAL NOW HAVING
CONFIRMED THAT THREE PEOPLE -- A
LOCAL REPORT THAT THREE PEOPLE
HAVE GONE FOR TREATMENT AT THAT
HOSPITAL.
NOT SURE IF BRIDGEPORT HAS
RECEIVED ANY INJURED BUT THEY
CERTAINLY GOT THE CALLS EARLY
THIS MORNING.
ALSO WANT TO LET YOU KNOW THAT
THE CHILDREN HAVE APPARENTLY
BEEN EVACUATED TO A NEARBY FIRE
HOUSE.
BUT INTERESTINGLY ENOUGH WERE IN
THAT SCHOOL.
SO MANY SCHOOLS HAVE A VERY
STRICT PROTOCOL FOR AN EMERGENCY
SITUATION IN WHICH THEY
BARRICADE THEMSELVES IN THE
CLASSROOMS AS BEST THEY CAN
STAYING LOW UNTIL THEY GET SOME
KIND OF INDICATION THAT IT'S
SAFE TO EVACUATE THE SCHOOL.
AS WE CONTINUE TO COLLECT MORE
INFORMATION, SHOOTING AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE GOING TO BRING IT TO YOU.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A QUICK
BREAK.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
♪
(Announcer) When Subaru owners
look in the mirror,
they see more than themselves.
So we celebrate our year-end
with the "share the love" event.
Get a great deal on a new Subaru
and 250 dollars goes to your
choice of five charities.
By the end of this, our fifth
year,
our total can reach almost 25
million dollars.
It's a nice reflection on us
all.
Now through January 2nd.
Social Security are just numbers
thinkin a budget.d...
Well, we worked hard for those
benefits.
We earned them.
And if Washington tries to cram
decisions about the future...
of these programs into a last
minute budget deal...
we'll all pay the price.
AARP is fighting to protect
seniors with responsible...
solutions that strengthen
Medicare and...
Social Security for generations
to come.
We can do better than a last
minute deal...
that would hurt all of us.
IS THE SAME FREQUENT HEARTBURN
TREATMENT AS PRILOSEC OTC.
NOW WITH A FANCY COATING
THAT GIVES YOU A BURST
OF WILDBERRY FLAVOR.
NOW WHY MAKE A FLAVORED
HEARTBURN PILL?
BECAUSE THIS IS AMERICA.
AND WE DON'T JUST
MAKE THINGS YOU WANT,
WE MAKE THINGS YOU
DIDN'T EVEN KNOW YOU WANTED.
LIKE A SPOON FORK.
SPRAY CHEESE.
AND JEANS MADE
OUT OF SWEATPANTS.
SO GRAB YOURSELF SOME
NEW PRILOSEC OTC WILDBERRY.
[ Male Announcer ]
ONE PILL EACH MORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBURN.
SATISFACTION GUARANTEED
OR YOUR MONEY BACK.
>>> WE'RE FOLLOWING BREAKING
NEWS AT SANDY HOOK IN NEWTOWN
BEI,
CONNECTICUT.
ON THE RIGHT-HAND SIDE OF YOUR
SCREEN, YOU CAN SEE A GURNEY.
AT THE TOP OF YOUR SCREEN YOU
CAN SEE THE EMERGENCY VEHICLES.
WE'RE TOLD ABOUT SIX AMBULANCES
ARE NOW ON THE SCENE AS WELL AS
NUMEROUS FIRST RESPONDERS AND
CANINE UNITS SEARCHING NOT ONLY
THE SCHOOL PROPERTY BUT THE
WOODS AS WELL THAT SURROUND IT.
AND ON YOUR LEFT-HAND SIDE OF
YOUR SCREEN IS AN AERIAL VIEW OF
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
LET'S LISTEN TO WFSB.
IN THIS SCENE RIGHT HERE IT
LOOKS A LITTLE MORE CALM BUT,
AGAIN, PEOPLE CLOSER IN HAVE
SAID IT HAS BEEN COMPLETELY
CHAOTIC AND THEY HAVE BEEN
WATCHING AS LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS HAVE BEEN RESPONDING
TO THE SCENE TRYING TO ASCERTAIN
HOW MANY PEOPLE ARE HURT AND
INJURED OR POSSIBLY DEAD AT THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> AND YOU CAN SEE THE LARGE
AREA SET UP THERE.
YOU CAN TELL FROM THE SHOT, THE
LIVE SHOT AS WE TAKE A LOOK AT
THE PICTURES FROM OUR
HELICOPTER.
YOU CAN GET AN IDEA AND REALLY
SEE IT HERE HOW MANY CROWN
VICTORIAS, STATE POLICE CRUISERS
ARE IN THIS SHOT.
THIS VEHICLE APPEARS TO BE SORT
OF THE CENTER OF THEIR FOCUS.
THAT IS RIGHT OUTSIDE OF THE
ENTRANCE TO THE SCHOOL, THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN.
TO GIVE PEOPLE AN IDEA OF WHERE
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT, IT'S
BETWEEN EXITS 10 AND 11 ON I-84
AS YOU HEAD WEST TOWARDS
DANBURY.
YOU CAN SEE THAT THIS IS A SHOT
OF THAT SCHOOL.
IT'S A K-4 SCHOOL AND THEY HAVE
ABOUT 600 STUDENTS AT THAT
SCHOOL.
THE CALL CAME IN AT 9:41 THIS
MORNING REPORTING THAT THERE HAD
BEEN A SHOOTING AT THAT SCHOOL
AND THAT POLICE WERE RESPONDING.
>> AND WE ARE HEARING, AGAIN,
FROM CBS NEWS WITH A REPORTER ON
THE SCENE HAS SAID AT LEAST ONE
SHOOTER HAS BEEN KILLED AND
THERE ARE SOME OTHER REPORTS
COMING OUT THAT IT'S BEING
LOOKED AT AS A DIFFERENT SCENE
NOW.
THE QUESTION IS, WAS IT ONE OR
TWO SHOOTERS.
WE DON'T KNOW YET.
AT LEAST ONE GUNMAN IS DEAD.
AGAIN, IF YOU'RE A PARENT AND
YOUR JUST JOINING US, THEY ARE
ASKING THAT YOU NOT GO TO THE
SCHOOL.
THIS IS LIVE ON THE GROUND THERE
AND JUST BY WATCHING THIS, ERIC,
I WOULD SAY THAT THE SCENE SEEMS
TO BE DIFFERENT THAN IT WAS 20
MINUTES AGO AND THAT WOULD BE AS
IF THEY ALREADY CAPTURED THE
GUNMAN, THINGS WOULD CHANGE.
>> YOU'RE WATCHING EYEWITNESS
NEWS COVERAGE.
KEEP UP WITH US ON OUR VERY
LATEST COVER RANL.
THIS IS A HELICOPTER FROM WCB.
WE KNOW ONE PERSON WAS
TRANSPORTED AND BOB FROM CBS
NEWS IS REPORTING THAT THE
GUNMAN IS DEAD THERE AT THE
SCENE.
>> I WANT TO BREAK INTO THAT
LOCAL COVERAGE AS YOU WERE
HEARING.
ONE OF THOSE VEHICLES IN THE
CENTER OF YOUR SCREEN, CENTER
TOP PORTION OF YOUR SCREEN IS
ROPED OFF.
MAYBE A VEHICLE OF INTEREST.
THERE ARE TACTICAL OFFICERS AS
WELL ON THE ROOF OF THE BUILDING
AND NOT ONLY THAT, THEY HAVE
BEEN LOOKING UP ON A HILLSIDE
BEHIND THE SCHOOL.
OFFICERS WITH CANINE UNITS HAVE
BEEN UP BEHIND THE SCHOOL.
THREE STATE TROOPERS, IN FACT,
LOOKING FOR SOMEONE OR SOMETHING
IN THE WOODS UP BEHIND THE
SCHOOL.
OUR SUSAN CANDIOTTI HAS RACED TO
THE SCENE AMID THE REPORTS OF
SHOTS FIRED.
SUSAN, CAN YOU HEAR ME?
>> Reporter: I CAN HEAR YOU AND
IT'S NOT A TERRIFIC CONNECTION.
WE UNDERSTAND FROM OUR SOURCE
WITH KNOWLEDGE OF THE
INVESTIGATION THAT THE SUSPECTED
SHOOTER IN THIS CASE IS DEAD, IS
DECEASED ON THE SCENE AND THAT
POLICE HAVE RECOVERED TWO
WEAPONS FROM HIM.
AGAIN, THIS IS ACCORDING TO OUR
SOURCE.
IT IS NOT KNOWN AT THIS TIME
WHETHER POLICE KILLED THE
SHOOTER OR WHETHER HE TOOK HIS
OWN LIFE.
THERE ARE ALSO UNCONFIRMED
REPORTS THAT ANOTHER SHOOTER
MIGHT BE ON THE SCENE -- MIGHT
REMAIN ON THE SCENE.
AGAIN, THAT IS UNCONFIRMED
INFORMATION AND AUTHORITIES ARE
TRYING TO SEE WHETHER THAT IS
THE CASE.
ASHLEIGH?
>> ANY INKLING FROM YOUR SOURCE
WHETHER THE SHOOTER IS A STUDENT
OR AN ADULT?
>> Reporter: I'VE BEEN TRYING TO
FIND OUT EXACTLY HOW THE SHOOTER
MADE ACCESS TO THE SCHOOL AND
WHERE THE BODY WAS FOUND.
BUT I DON'T VERY THAT
INFORMATION YET.
AS WELL AS WHETHER THERE ARE
OTHER INJURIES.
THERE ARE UNCONFIRMED REPORTS,
ACCORDING TO THE SOURCE, OF
MULTIPLE INJURIES AND WE'RE
GETTING SOME INFORMATION THAT
YOU'VE BEEN HEARING, OF COURSE,
THIS MORNING.
BUT MY SOURCE DOESN'T HAVE ANY
OF THAT CONFIRMED AS TO HOW MANY
PEOPLE MIGHT HAVE BEEN INJURED.
>> AND WHAT ABOUT THE CAR THAT
SEEMED TO BE THE FOCUS OF THE
INVESTIGATORS ON THE SCENE?
THERE'S A CAR THAT IS
ERRATICALLY PARKED AND MARKED
OFF WITH CRIME TAPE.
ANY INFORMATION THAT THAT IS
CONNECTED TO THIS?
>> Reporter: NO DETAILS ON THAT
AS OF YET.
I HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE TO SEE FOR
MYSELF.
SO WE ARE -- WE'LL GET THERE AS
SOON AS WE CAN.
OBVIOUSLY THERE'S A LARGE POLICE
PRESENCE ON THE SCENE.
AGAIN, REPEATING HERE THAT THE
SHOOTER, SUSPECTED SHOOTER IN
THIS CASE IS DEAD.
EITHER TAKEN DOWN BY POLICE OR
HE MAY HAVE TAKEN HIS OWN LIFE.
THAT REMAINS UNCLEAR AT THIS
POINT.
>> I JUST WANT TO BRING IN AS
WELL, SOME OF THE REPORTS HAVE
BEEN COMING IN FROM LOCAL
NEWSPAPERS, SOME OF THE LOCAL
AFFILIATES.
THE NEWTOWN B AND MULTIPLE
REPORTS OF INJURIES AFTER THIS
SHOOTING AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
I WANT TO JUST DIP IN OUR
AFFILIATE COVERAGE.
>> WE DO NOT HAVE THAT CONFIRMED
YET BUT WE'RE STILL TRYING TO
DETERMINE THAT.
THE INFORMATION IS JUST GOING
OUT TO THE PARENTS.
A LOT OF THEM ARE UPSET AS THEY
ARE TRYING TO PICK UP THEIR
CHILDREN.
THERE IS A LOT OF CONFUSION AND
CARS JAMMED IN HERE AND PEOPLE
JUST CAN'T GET CLOSE ENOUGH TO
GET SOME SOLID INFORMATION BUT
THAT IS GOING TO BE COMING AS
THEY SECURE THE SCENE.
>> ROBERT, THEY ARE REPORTING OR
CONFIRMING THAT ONE GUNMAN IS
DEAD.
IS THERE ANY INDICATION AS
YOU'RE OUT THERE AND HEARING
PEOPLE AROUND YOU THAT THERE
COULD BE ANOTHER SHOOTER?
>> WELL, THERE WAS SOME
INFORMATION THAT SOMEBODY -- AT
LEAST ONE PARENT SAW SOMEBODY
BEING ESCORTED OUT OF THIS
WOODED AREA RIGHT OVER HERE WITH
POLICE AND THAT THAT PERSON
TURNED TO A PARENT AND SAID, IT
WASN'T ME.
THE PERSON WAS JIBED DESCRIBED
WEARING A CAMMO TYPE SHIRT.
THE PERSON IS BEING HELD IN ONE
OF THE POLICE CARS OVER HERE TO
THE LEFT.
AT THIS POINT WE DON'T KNOW IF
THAT PERSON IS CONNECTED AND WE
ARE STILL TRYING TO DETERMINE
SOME EXACT INFORMATION ABOUT
WHETHER THERE IS ONE GUNMAN, TWO
GUNMAN, OR MORE AND IF SOMEBODY
IS DEAD WHO IS RESPONSIBLE FOR
THESE SHOOTINGS INSIDE THE
SCHOOL HERE.
BUT, AGAIN, WE ARE JUST TRYING
TO GET A SENSE OF WHAT EXACTLY
HAPPENED INSIDE AND I THINK THAT
POLICE ARE OF COURSE SWARMING
THE AREA MAKING SURE THAT WE
ALSO SAW SOME FEDERAL AGENTS
FROM THE ATF ARMED WITH HEAVY
GUNS TRYING TO ASSIST THE
NEWTOWN POLICE AND, OF COURSE,
THE STATE POLICE.
>> ALL RIGHT, ROBERT, WE'LL
CHECK IN WITH YOU IN A MOMENT.
LET'S RECAP WHAT WE KNOW.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY, 600 OR SO
STUDENTS.
THERE WAS A SHOOTING REPORTED AT
9:41 A.M.
THAT'S WHEN A CALL CAME IN TO
911.
WE CAN CONFIRM AT LEAST ONE
PERSON HAS BEEN SHOT AT THAT
SCHOOL.
WE ALSO HAVE BOB ORR FROM CBS
NEWS, JUSTICE CORRESPONDENT FROM
CBS NEWS, HE HAS BEEN REPORTING
THAT THE GUNMAN IS DEAD.
>> THE PICTURE THAT IS MAKING
ITS WAY ON OUR AIR, THE SYMBOL
OF WHAT HAS BEEN HAPPENING,
WE'VE BEEN SEEING THE CHILDREN
LED AWAY CRYING, LED AWAY FROM
THEIR ELEMENTARY SCHOOL CRYING
AS THEY ARE WALKING OUT AND
ADULTS TRYING TO KEEP THEM SAFE.
NOW THE SCHOOL IS GOING THROUGH
THE EFFORT OF TRYING TO REUNITE
THE STUDENTS WHO HAVE BEEN TAKEN
TO THE NEARBY FIREHOUSE WITH THE
PARENTS WHO HAVE BEEN LINING UP
THERE.
THE SCHOOL IS TRYING TO KEEP
PARENTS INFORMED THERE AND AT
THE SAME TIME THEY ARE ASKING
PARENTS NOT TO GO TO THE SCHOOL.
>> YOU CAN IMAGINE WHAT KIND OF
EX CRUCIAL ATING REQUEST THAT IS
THAT THEY ARE ASKING THAT YOU
WAIT FOR THEM.
BUSES HAVE BEEN CANCEL LTD.
NO BUSES ARE RUNNING AT THIS
POINT.
THOSE ARE S.W.A.T. OFFICERS.
THEY HAVE THEIR HELMET AND
CAMOUFLAGE ON.
THEY ARE GATHERING OUTSIDE OF
THE FRONT DOOR.
WHAT WE DO KNOW AT THIS POINT IS
THAT THE ENTIRE AREA IS IN
LOCKDOWN.
ONE GENTLEMAN HAS BEEN TAKEN
INTO CUSTODY AT LEAST THEY WANT
TO TALK TO HIM.
HE WAS TELLING A PARENT THAT HE
WAS NOT INVOLVED.
THAT'S WHAT POLICE DO, THEY LOCK
THE ENTIRE DOWN AND GET ANYONE
THEY WANT TO TALK TO AND TRY TO
FIGURE OUT WHAT IS GOING ON.
>> ESPECIALLY WHEN SOMEONE IS ON
THE SCENE LIKE THIS WEARING
CAMOUFLAGE.
GUNS WERE STILL DRAWN AND THE
LAST REPORT WE HAD FROM HIM JUST
A FEW MOMENTS AGO WAS SAYING
THAT THINGS WERE NOT GETTING
BETTER.
THAT THIS IS A BAD SCENE.
THE HOSPITALS, WE KNOW, HAVE
BEEN PREPARED ALTHOUGH WE'RE
HEARING THAT THE HOSPITAL IN
BRIDGEPORT HAS NOW SAID THAT
IT'S NOT EXPECTING ANYONE COMING
TO THE BRIDGEPORT HOSPITAL.
AS FAR AS WHO EXACTLY HAS BEEN
SHOT, THE NUMBER OF PEOPLE
INJURED, WE DO NOT KNOW.
WE'RE HANGING ON TO THE VERY
OMINOUS WORDS OF LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE FROM THE STATE POLICE.
>> AS WE CONTINUE TO LISTEN IN
TO SOME OF THE LOCAL COVERAGE
AND WATCHING FROM THESE
HELICOPTER SHOTS AS THE NUMEROUS
POLICE RESPONSE BEGINS TO WHAT
LOOKS LIKE HEAD TOWARDS ONE
LOCATION OF THE SCHOOL.
I CAN TELL YOU THE HEADLINE, A
SOURCE TELLS OUR SUSAN CANDIOTTI
THAT THE GUNMAN, THE SHOOTER IS
DEAD ON THE SCENE AND APPARENTLY
TWO WEAPONS HAVE ARE BEEN
RECOVERED.
WE ARE NOT CLEAR AS TO WHETHER
THE SHOOTER IS A CHILD OR AN
ADULT.
WE HAVE UNCONFIRMED REPORTS THAT
THERE IS A SECOND SHOOTER.
POLICE WERE SEARCHING IN THE
HILLSIDE BEHIND THE SCHOOL IN
THE WOODED AREA WITH THE CANINE
UNIT AS WELL AS PARENTS FLOODED
INTO THE PARKING LOT BEFORE THE
WORD CAME OUT THAT THEY WERE TO
STAY HOME, STAY BY THE PHONE,
THAT IT PERHAPS WASN'T SAFE TO
BE THERE.
POLICE TELLING NEWS 8 THAT THEY
SAW A CHILD WITH A BLOODY FACE
AND ANOTHER CHILD WITH A HAND
INJURY.
AND ONE OTHER PIECE OF
INFORMATION I WANT TO PASS YOUR
WAY BEFORE WE HEAD TO A QUICK
BREAK AND THAT IS THE HOSPITAL
AT YALE, YALE IS IN NEW HAVEN
WHICH IS ABOUT A 40-MINUTE DRIVE
FROM THIS LOCATION, THAT
HOSPITAL HAS READIED ITSELF FOR
SOMETHING CALLED AN EMERGENCY
TRIAGE UNIT WHICH RESPONDS TO
MASS CASUALTY UNITS.
WE'RE TAKING A QUICK BREAK AND
WE'RE BACK RIGHT AFTER THIS.
WHO THINKS TWO
IS BETTER THAN ONE?
SO ALL OF YOU DO.
YES, FOR SURE.
NOW WHAT'S BETTER?
BEING ABLE TO SHOOT TWO LASERS
OUT OF BOTH OF YOUR EYES
AT THE SAME TIME
OR JUST ONE LASER
OUT OF ONE EYE?
[ all kids ] TWO!
[ Moderator ] OKAY, WHY?
IF IT'S JUST ONE BEAM -- OKAY,
IT DOES A LITTLE BIT OF DAMAGE.
TWO BEAMS -- IT WILL
MAKE SOMETHING EXPLODE!
AND THAT'S MORE FUN?
YEAH!
AND IT'S MORE POWERFUL
YOU'RE SAYING?
YEAH!
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S NOT COMPLICATED.
DOING TWO THINGS AT ONCE
IS BETTER.
AND ONLY AT&T'S NETWORK
LETS YOU TALK AND SURF
ON YOUR IPHONE 5.
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
Almost nothing can dampen
a baby's mood,
when he wakes up dry
in Pampers.
Unlike other diapers,
Pampers has 3 absorbent layers,
for up to 12 hours
of protection overnight,
and more beautiful mornings.
♪
Pampers. Peaceful Nights.
Playful Days.
>>> SO I CAN CONFIRM FOR YOU
SOME FURTHER DETAILS IN THIS
SHOOTING THAT WE'RE FOLLOWING IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, A SCHOOL THAT HAS ABOUT
600 STUDENTS FROM KINDERGARTEN
THROUGH FOURTH GRADE.
NOT LONG AFTER SCHOOL BEGAN,
APPARENTLY SHOTS RANK RANG OUT.
POLICE WERE CALLED IMMEDIATELY.
THERE IS ONE PERSON DEAD ON THE
SCENE, THE SHOOTER, IN FACT.
WHAT I CAN'T TELL YOU IS IF THE
SHOOTER IS A CHILDREN OR AN
ADULT.
BUT TWO WEAPONS, ACCORDING TO
SUSAN CANDIOTTI, WERE REQUIRED
AT THE SCENE AS WELL.
ONE OF THEM A BLOCK.
WE CAN CONFIRM THAT TWO WEAPONS,
A REPORT OF PERHAPS ANOTHER
SHOOTER.
MANY OF THEM RUSHED TO THE
SCHOOL TO GET THEIR CHILDREN.
BEFORE POLICE TOLD THEM THEY
NEEDED TO STAY HOME.
THAT THIS WAS AN ACTIVE
INVESTIGATION.
MANY CAN CANINE UNITS WERE UP ON
THE HILL IN THE BRUSH SEARCHING
FOR SOMETHING.
WHETHER IT WAS EVIDENCE OR THE
REPORTED SHOOTER.
SIX AMBULANCES, ONE APPARENTLY
WITNESSED TAKING ONE OF THE
CHILDREN AWAY AND I CAN ALSO
TELL YOU THAT THERE WAS A
WITNESS WHO TOLD NEWS 8
CONNECTICUT THAT SHE SAW TWO
CHILDREN.
ONE OF THE CHILDREN WITH A
BLOODY FACE AND ANOTHER WITH
WHAT APPEARED TO BE A HAND
INJURY.
ALL OF THE CHILDREN NOW
EVACUATED TO A LOCAL FIRESTATION
NEARBY AND THE ENTIRE SCHOOL
DISTRICT IN NEWTOWN IS UNDER
LOCKDOWN.
I'M JOINED BY THE MAYOR.
CAN YOU HEAR ME.
>> I'M THE MAYOR OF DANBURY.
>> MAYOR OF DANBURY.
A I APOLOGIZE.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU'VE BEEN
PRIVY TO ANY INFORMATION THAT
HAS BEEN SHARED.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL US?
>> WELL, I CAN TELL YOU THAT,
FIRST OF ALL, OBVIOUSLY OUR
HEARTS AND PRAYERS GO OUT TO THE
VICTIMS OF THIS HORRIBLE
INCIDENT.
WE HAVE MUTUAL AID AGREEMENTS IN
PLACE THAT ALLOW US TO PROVIDE
ASSETS THAT THEY MAY NOT HAVE
ALONG WITH THE STATE POLICE THAT
HAS TAKEN THE LEAD ON THIS
INVESTIGATION.
THREE OF OUR VICTIMS ARE AT THE
HOSPITAL IN DANBURY AND THEY ARE
CURRENTLY BEING TREATED.
I CAN'T TELL YOU THE STATUS.
I CAN ONLY TELL YOU THAT IT'S
VERY SERIOUS.
>> CAN YOU TELL ME, MAYOR
BOUGHTON IF THEY ARE CHILDREN OR
ADULTS?
WAS THIS A STAFF INCIDENT OR AN
INCIDENT WITH THE CHILDREN?
>> I HATE TO DO THIS TO YOU.
I KNOW YOU WANT TO GET THAT
INFORMATION OUT.
ALL OF THIS IS STILL UNDER
INVESTIGATION.
I CAN'T DISCLOSE THAT
INFORMATION UNDER HIPPA
REGULATIONS.
>> CAN I INTERRUPT YOU FOR A
MOMENT.
I WANT TO GO TO AN INTERVIEW
WITH A MOTHER AND CHILD WITH OUR
AFFILIATE.
>> RECOUNTING WHAT IS GOING ON,
JOINING ME IS ALEXIS WHO IS IN
THIRD GRADE AND YOU SAW A LOT OF
WHAT WAS GOING ON?
>> WELL, WE FOUND ALL OF THESE
PEOPLE AND THERE WAS LIKE RIGHT
NEAR THE WINDOW IN OUR CLASSROOM
AND WE SAW A POLICE OFFICERS AND
WE HEARD THEM ON THE ROOF AND IN
OUR BUILDING.
>> WAS EVERYBODY CRYING, SCARED,
WANTING THEIR PARENTS TO COME
GET THEM?
>> YEAH, THEY WERE.
AND THEN SOME PEOPLE WERE EVEN
LIKE, THEY KIND OF GOT A STOMACH
ACHE.
>> DID YOU HEAR ANY GUNSHOTS OR
ANYTHING LIKE THAT?
>> WELL, POLICE OFFICERS, LIKE
THEY WERE KIND OF BECAUSE THEY
ARE POLICE OFFICERS RIGHT OUT
THE DOOR LIKE TRYING TO FIND THE
GUY.
>> ARE YOU OKAY RIGHT NOW?
>> YEAH.
>> ARE YOU SURE?
>> UH-HUH.
>> HOW EXCITED WERE YOU TO SEE
DAD?
>> EXCITED.
>> DAD, YOU LOOK WORSE THAN HER,
I'VE GOT TO TELL YOU.
>> YEAH.
SHOCKING.
I GOT THE CALL AT WORK THIS
MORNING AND I CAN'T BELIEVE A
SMALL TOWN LIKE THIS WOULD EVER
HAVE ANYTHING LIKE THIS HAPPEN
AND TO BE IN AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, IT'S UNHEARD OF.
>> K THROUGH 4.
>> YES.
>> AND YOU SAY THERE ARE 600
KIDS IN THERE?
>> YES.
ROUGHLY AROUND 600.
>> WHAT WAS GOING THROUGH YOUR
MIND?
YOU IMMEDIATELY THINK OF YOUR
CHILD.
>> YES.
I WAS PRETTY SHAKEN UP.
DIDN'T KNOW WHO OR WHAT
HAPPENED.
I KNEW THERE WERE SHOOTERS IN
THE BUILDING OR A SHOOTER.
JUST WORRIED ABOUT WHO ELSE IS
LOCKED IN THE BUILDING AT THIS
TIME.
>> MOM, WHAT DO YOU THINK ABOUT
THIS SCENE IN NEWTOWN?
>> IT JUST DOESN'T SEEM REAL.
LIKE IT'S NOT EVEN POSSIBLE.
YOU READ IT IN THE PAPER OR SEE
IT IN THE NEWS, YOU'RE LIKE, OH,
MY GOD, THAT POOR FAMILY AND
THEN YOU HAVE SOMETHING HAPPEN
SO CLOSE TO HOME, I THINK I'M
STILL IN SHOCK, TO BE HONEST
WITH YOU.
I'M LIKE, LET'S GET HER CELL
PHONE ACTIVATED RIGHT NOW.
>> NEWS 8, WE HAVE EXCLUSIVE
VIDEO OF A SUSPECT WALKING AWAY
IN CUFFS.
DOES THIS PUT YOU AT EASE AT ALL
IN.
>> NO, NOT AT ALL.
I'M NOT SURE IF THERE'S --
THERE'S PROBABLY MORE PEOPLE IN
THE BUILDING.
>> WHAT ARE THE PARENTS SAYING?
EVERYBODY IS GROUPING TOGETHER
AND TALKING AND PUTTING EACH
OTHER AT EASE.
>> WE'RE COPING.
WE'RE STILL TRYING TO FIND OUT
WHAT IS GOING ON.
IT'S A LITTLE NERVE RACKING.
AS YOU CAN TELL BEHIND US, WE DO
HAVE A FEW MORE CARS PULLING IN
AT THIS TIME.
HOW MANY SHOOTERS, HOW MANY
PEOPLE ARE INJURED.
>>.
>> Reporter: I SAW A PARENT
RUNNING AND CRYING AT THE BOTTOM
OF THE HILL WANTING TO FIND HIS
CHILD.
DID YOU HAVE ANY PROBLEM FINDING
ALEXIS?
>> I DIDN'T HAVE TOO MUCH
TROUBLE.
OBVIOUSLY I WAS RUNNING TO THE
SCHOOL.
SOMEBODY TOLD ME THAT THE KIDS
WERE EVACUATED -- MOST OF THE
KIDS WERE EVACUATED TO THE LOCAL
FIREHOUSE HERE.
INSIDE THE FIREHOUSE IT WAS
OBVIOUSLY TOUGH TO FIND BECAUSE
IT WAS PACKED.
BUT SHE WAS THERE AND WE'RE
GRATEFUL.
>> Reporter: YEAH.
AGAIN, IT'S PROBABLY A MORE
NERVE-RACKING SCENE FOR A
PARENT, KEITH, THAN THE KIDS AT
THIS POINT.
THEY WERE THERE.
THEY ARE SAFE NOW.
BUT EVERY SINGLE PARENT THAT
I'VE SPOKEN TO -- AND THERE'S A
MILLION OF THEM, ARE JUST SHAKEN
UP AND WANT ANSWERS IMMEDIATELY.
OF COURSE, NEWS 8 WILL BE HERE
LIVE FOR ALL OF THE DAY UNTIL WE
HAVE SOME ANSWERS FOR YOU.
I'LL SEND IT BACK OVER TO YOU.
>> AS THEY WRAP UP THAT LOCATION
ON LOCATION, OUR LOCAL AFFILIATE
WRAPPING UP THEIR INTERVIEW WITH
AELECTS IS S
AELECTS ALEXIS.
SHE HEARD THE SOUND OF THEM ON
THE ROOF AND WHAT SHE SAW, IT
CONFERS WITH WHAT WE'RE
REPORTING, THAT S.W.A.T. TEAM
WAS ON THE ROOF AS WELL AND
CANINE UNITS AROUND THE SCHOOL
AS WELL.
ONE OF THE THINGS THAT WE
HAVEN'T SEEN YET IT A REPORTED
VIDEO OF SOMEONE BEING TAKEN
AWAY IN HANDCUFFS.
I CAN TELL THAT YOU SUSAN
CANDIOTTI HAS CONFIRMED THAT THE
SHOOTER IS DEAD ON THE SCENE.
WHETHER IN FACT THERE WAS A
SECOND PERSON WHO WAS ARRESTED
HAS NOT YET BEEN CONFIRMED.
THE MAYOR OF DANBURY, MARK
BOUGHTON IS ON THE PHONE WITH
US.
>> A TEACHER WAS SHOT IN THE
FOOT AND THAT TEACHER WAS TAKEN
TO DANBURY HOSPITAL.
THAT IS ONE INJURY THAT WE'RE
HEARING FROM MULTIPLE SOURCES
AND NOW THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
CONFIRMING THAT.
>> WE HEARD THAT DANBURY
HOSPITAL AS WELL AS BRIDGEPORT
HOSPITAL HAVE BEEN ON STAND BY
FOR THE POSSIBILITY OF MULTIPLE
VICTIMS BEING HOSPITALIZED.
WE HAVE CONFIRMED AND IT'S
LIKELY THE SAME PERSON HEADED TO
BRIDGEPORT HOSPITAL, WE HAVE
CONFIRMED THAT THE NEWTOWN
AMBULANCE TRANSPORTED ONE PERSON
THAT WAS SHOT IN THE FOOT TO
THAT HOSPITAL.
THEY ARE ON THE WAY TO
BRIDGEPORT HOSPITAL WHERE THEY
WILL BE TREATED.
THAT PERSON IS IN STABLE
CONDITION.
>> AND WE DO SEE -- I SAW A
STRETCHER THERE.
IT WAS UNCLEAR WHAT WAS ON TOP
OF THAT.
BUT WE ARE LOOKING AT LIVE
AERIAL PICTURES FROM OUR WCBS
HELICOPTER, OUR SISTER STATION
IN NEW YORK THAT IS FLYING OVER
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AGAIN, THE NIGHTMARE BEGAN AT 20
MINUTES BEFORE 10:00 ON THIS
FRIDAY MORNING WHEN THEY GOT
REPORTS OF A SCHOOL SHOOTING AT
THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL THAT GOES
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH THE FOURTH
GRADE.
THE NEARBY FIREHOUSE, AS THE
CROWS FLY, IT'S AERIAL SHOTS.
IT'S NOT FAR AWAY.
THAT'S BECOME THE STAGING
SITUATION WHERE PARENTS HAVE
BEEN SHOWING UP.
I BELIEVE THAT'S WHAT WE'RE
LOOKING AT NOW.
PARENTS HAVE BEEN SHOWING UP
THERE AND REUNITING WITH THEIR
CHILDREN, TAKING THEM HOME.
AND AS ROBERT SAID, WHEN HE WAS
WATCHING THEM REUNITE, THE
CHILDREN WERE QUITE SHAKEN.
THEY WERE LED AWAY CRYING AND
THIS IS GOING TO BE A VERY, VERY
DIFFICULT THING TO EXPLAIN TO
THESE YOUNG CHILDREN.
>> AND WE DID SEE OBVIOUSLY A
LOT OF THAT EMOTION AND WE SAW
FROM THE PARENTS AS THEY ARRIVED
HERE JUST IN THIS SHOT THAT WE
HAVE HAD UP FOR THE LAST SEVERA
EMBRACING AS THEY WERE ARRIVING
THERE AT THE SCENE.
ROBERT IS THERE ON THE SCENE AS
IS LYNN BESTOFF.
THEY'RE THERE RIGHT NOW.
>> THEY'RE INTERVIEWING SOME OF
THE PARENT WHO IS CAN HAVE COME
TO
TO THE SCENE.
LET'S LISTEN.
>> THERE'S SIGNING PROCEDURES.
I BELIEVE THE FRONT DOOR IS
LOCKED DURING THE DAY, TOO.
I'M CURIOUS TO SEE HOW THESE
PEOPLE DID GET INTO THE
BUILDING.
>> ANY IDEA AT ALL AND ANYTHING
THAT PEOPLE ARE HEARING?
>> FROM WHAT WE'VE SEEN IT'S
IMPOSSIBLE TO GET INTO A SCHOOL,
ESPECIALLY AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
TODAY WITHOUT PEOPLE CHECKING,
CHECKING AND RECHECKING WHO YOU
ARE AND IF YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO BE
THERE.
>> CORRECT.
I WOULD GUESS THEY WOULD HAVE
PICKED UP ON -- UNLESS IT'S
SOMEBODY THEY KNEW THEY LET INTO
THE BUILDING.
>> RIGHT.
YOUR DAUGHTER FOR A THIRD GRADER
SEEMS VERY CALM RIGHT NOW.
DO YOU THINK THAT THIS HASN'T
HIT HER YET?
>> I DON'T THINK SO.
WHEN I P PICKED HER UP, THOUGH,
SHE WAS REALLY, REALLY UPSET AND
EMOTIONAL ABOUT IT.
WE'RE JUST FORTUNATE ENOUGH THAT
SHE'S HERE WITH US.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR JOINING
US.
THANK YOU FOR BRINGING YOUR
DAUGHTER TO SPEAK TO US, AND WE,
OF COURSE, KEITH, WILL LET THESE
PEOPLE KNOW EXACTLY WHAT'S GOING
ON AS SOON AS WE GET WORD.
>> OKAY.
A COUPLE OF THINGS TO GET YOU UP
TO SPEED ON.
ONE OF THE AFFILIATES, WFSB IS
REPORTING THAT A TEACHER
APPARENTLY HAS BEEN SHOT IN THE
FOOT AND WAS TAKEN TO DANBURY
HOSPITAL ABOUT 10, 15 MINUTES
AWAY.
THE MAYOR OF DANBURY HAS BEEN ON
THE PHONE WITH US, MARK, AND I
THINK WE MIGHT HAVE LOST HIM.
WE'LL SEE IF WE CAN'T GET
RECONNECTED WITH HIM AT ONE
POINT.
ALSO, VERY, VERY IMPORTANT
INFORMATION, AND THAT IS THAT
ANY ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IS LOCKED
FOR THE MOST PART ACROSS THIS
COUNTRY, AND IT IS NEXT TO
IMPOSSIBLE TO ENTER AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WITHOUT BEING
BUZZED IN AND HAVE YOUR IDENTITY
CHECKED IN SOME WAY.
HOW DID THE SHOOTER HAVE THE
ACCESS TO THIS SCHOOL?
THAT'S GOING TO BE SOMETHING
THAT CLEARLY THERE'S GOING TO BE
A LOT OF QUESTIONS ASKED.
JASON CARROLL WITH SOMETHING
NEW?
>> YEAH, I DID.
ONE OF THE OUR AFFILIATES IN
NEW YORK NOW REPORTING THAT
THERE ARE WHAT THEY'RE REPORTING
MULTIPLE FATALITIES INVOLVED IN
THE SHOOTING AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
NO MORE SPECIFICS OTHER THAN
USING THAT SPECIFIC TERM,
MULTIPLE FATALITIES.
>> GOOD LORD.
OUR SUSAN CANDIOTTI HAS A SOURCE
THAT CONFIRMED TO CNN THAT
SHOOTER -- I HESITATE GUNMAN
BECAUSE WE DON'T KNOW IF IT'S A
STUDE
STUDENT.
THIS SCHOOL GOES UP TO THE
FOURTH GRADE.
THE SHOOTER IS DEAD ON THE SEEN.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A QUICK
BREAK AND SEE WHAT ELSE WE CAN
GET FROM OUR SOURCES.
BACK IN A MOMENT.
[ bells dinging ]
♪ HARK HOW THE BELLS,
SWEET SILVER BELLS ♪
♪ ALL SEEM TO SAY
THROW CARE AWAY ♪
♪ FROM EVERYWHERE,
FILLING THE AIR ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
CHEX PARTY MIX.
EASY 15-MINUTE
HOMEMADE RECIPES
YOU JUST POP IN A MICROWAVE.
LIKE CARAMEL CHOCOLATE
DRIZZLES.
HAPPIER HOLIDAYS.
CHEX PARTY MIX.
GOVERNOR OF GETTING IT DONE.
YOU KNOW HOW TO DANCE...
WITH A DEADLINE.
AND YOU...RENT FROM NATIONAL.
BECAUSE ONLY NATIONAL LETS YOU
CHOOSE ANY CAR IN THE AISLE...
AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE A FULL-SIZE
OR ABOVE,
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
THIS IS AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS, BUSINESS PRO.
YES, IT IS.
GO NATIONAL. GO LIKE A PRO.
>>> SO WE'RE CONTINUING OUR
BREAKING NEWS.
OUR COVERAGE OF THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY COOL?
NEW TOWN, CONNECTICUT, 600 KIDS
BETWEEN KINDERGARTEN AND FOURTH
GRADE AND REPORTS OF A SHOOTING
AT THIS SCHOOL.
AFTER 9:40 IN THE MORNING THREE
VICTIMS IN THE HOSPITAL IN
SERIOUS CONDITION.
WE ALSO KNOW THAT THE SHOOTER,
DEAD ON THE SCENE ACCORDING TO A
SOURCE TELLING CNN.
JASON CARROLL WITH INFORMATION
FROM THE HOSPITAL.
>> THIS IS FROM DANBURY HOSPITAL
WHERE THEY HAD RECEIVED THREE
PATIENTS, STATEMENT FROM THE
SPOKESPERSON SAYING WE'RE HERE
TO CARE FOR ANY VICTIMS AND
THEIR FAMILIES IN ANY WAY THINK
NEED IT.
OUR HEARTS AND PRAYERS ARE
EXTENDED TO ANYONE INVOLVED IN
THIS TERRIBLE TRAGEDY TO DATE.
THREE PATIENTS HAVE BEEN
TRANSPORTED TO DANBURY HOSPITAL
FROM THE SCENE OUT OF AN
ABUNDANCE OF CAUTION AND NOT
BECAUSE OF A DIRECT THREAT,
DANBURY HOSPITAL IS UNDER
LOCKDOWN.
THIS ALLOWS US TO FOCUS ON THE
IMPORTANT WORK AT HAND.
THAT COMING FROM THE
SPOKESPERSON FROM DANBURY
HOSPITAL.
>> POSSIBLY THOSE INJURIES THE
RESULT OF TWO WEAPONS THAT WERE
RECOVERED FROM THE SCENE BY
POLICE.
A SOURCE TELLING CNN THOSE TWO
WEAPONS, A GLOCK AND A SIG
SAUER.
WE DON'T KNOW AT THIS TIME ABOUT
THE INJURIES THEMSELVES, WHETHER
THEY ARE CHILDREN OR WHETHER
THEY ARE STAFF OR ADULTS.
WE ALSO DON'T KNOW IF THE
SHOOTER THAT WAS KILLED ON THE
SCENE BY POLICE IS A CHILD OR AN
ADULT.
WE DO KNOW THAT THERE WAS ONE
AREA WHERE A CAR SEEMED TO BE
PARKED ERRATICALLY AND ROPED OFF
WITH CRIME TAPE.
IT WAS A SUBJECT OF INTEREST.
THE PICTURES WE SEE SHOW IT IS A
SOMEWHAT CALM SITUATION IT SEEMS
IN THE PARKING LOT.
SIX AMBULANCES AT THE MINIMUM
DISPATCHED TO THE SCENE, GURNEYS
WHEELED IN THE PARKING LOT INTO
THE SCHOOL.
REPORTS OF MULTIPLE INJURIES AT
THE TIME.
A STAGING AREA SET UP A
RESTAURANT CLOSE BY CALLED THE
VILLE AA RESTAURANT AND PIZZA WE
PARENTS WERE ASKED TO GO.
THE PARENTS ARE HOLDING THEIR
CHILDREN, BUT THEY PROBABLY LEFT
BEFORE THEY GOT THE INFORMATION
THAT LOCAL POLICE WERE ASKING
THEM DO NOT COME HERE.
IT WASN'T A SECURE LOCATION.
ASKING THEM TO STAY BY THE PHONE
INSTEAD AND ACTUALLY S.W.A.T.
TEAMS WITH KA NEEN UNITS NOT
ONLY ON THE ROOF OF THE SCHOOL
BUT IN THE WOODED AREA YOU SEE
BEHIND THE PARKING LOT, A HILL
BEHIND THE SCHOOL APPARENTLY THE
SUBJECT OF AN INTENSE SEARCH.
THERE WAS A REPORT OF A SECOND
GUNMAN BEING POSSIBLE, NOT
CONFIRMED.
WE HAVE A HUGE POLICE PRESENCE
AND A LOT OF EMERGENCY VEHICLES
THAT RESPONDED TO THIS SCENE.
THREE HOSPITALS ENACTING THEIR
EMERGENCY PROCEDURES, THEY'RE
TRAUMA TEAMS GETTING INTO
ACTION.
DANBURY HOSPITAL, BRIDGEPORT
HOSPITAL, YALE NEW HAVEN
HOSPITAL ALL SURROUNDING THIS
AREA WITHIN ABOUT A 100-MILE
RADIUS.
AS FAR AS THE NUMBER OF INJURED,
THE NATURE OF THE INJURIES,
WE'RE TOLD VERY SERIOUS, AT
LEAST THE THREE THAT WERE IN
DANBURY HOSPITAL VERY SERIOUS
INJURIES.
THE MAYOR OF DANBURY UNABLE TO
CONFIRM FOR US, HOWEVER, WHETHER
THOSE THREE INJURED PEOPLE ARE
CHILDREN OR IF THEY ARE ADULTS.
A WITNESS, THOUGH, TOLD A LOCAL
AFFILIATE, NEWS 8, THAT SHE SAW
TWO CHILDREN, ONE OF THEM WITH A
BLOODY FACE AND THE OTHER WITH
WHAT APPEARED TO BE A HAND
INJURY.
OTHER WITNESSES REPORTED
NUMEROUS GUNSHOT WOUNDS AT LEAST
THAT ONE OF THESE VICTIMS HAD