♪
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
SIGNS LIKE THE ONE YOU JUST SAW
ALL OVER NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
PE
PEOPLE SAYING OUR HEARTS ARE
BROKEN, BUT ARE STRONG.
CANDLES AND STUFFED ANIMALS AND
FLOWERS REMEMBERING THOSE WHO
HAVE LOST THEIR LIVES AND
REMEMBERING A TOWN, A PEACEFUL
TOWN THAT HAS NOW BEEN FOREVER
CHANGE
CHANGED.
I'M SOLEDAD O'BRIEN WITH WOLF
BLITZER THIS MORNING.
TRYING TO MAKE SENSE OF
SOMETHING THAT IS FRANKLY
IMPOSSIBLE TO UNDERSTAND.
FRIDAY'S TRAGEDY.
TODAY MAY MARK THE VERY FIRST
DAY OF HEALING FOR PEOPLE WHO
WILL BE FACING A VERY, VERY LONG
PROCESS.
THE ENTIRE COMMUNITY THAT ARE
DIRECTLY AFFECTED AND FOR THE
ENTIRE NATION, FAMILY, FRIENDS,
NEIGHBORS ALL GATHERING AT
PLACES OF WORSHIP IN THIS SMALL
SOUTHWESTERN CONNECTICUT TOWN.
A CANDLELIGHT VIGIL BEING
SCHEDULED FOR THIS EVENING.
PRESIDENT OBAMA EXPECTED TO FLY
IN THIS AFTERNOON AND AFTER
MEETING WITH THE FAMILIES OF
VICTIMS AND AFTER MEETING WITH
THE FIRST RESPONDERS HE WILL
TAKE PART IN THAT CANDLELIGHT
VIGIL.
OFFICIALS WHO HAVE BEEN GIVING
US INFORMATION EVER SINCE FRIDAY
AFTERNOON.
WE'RE ENXPECTING TO HEAR FROM TE
STATE POLICE AND THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER WHO TOLD US HE WAS
GOING TO WRAP UP THE AUTOPSIES
ON THE SHOOTER AND THE SHOOTER'S
MOTHER AND ALSO THE FOCUS OF
THEIR INVESTIGATION WOULD NOW BE
THE WEAPONRY.
WE'RE EXPECTING AN UPDATE IN THE
NEXT FEW MINUTES.
THEY HAVE ALREADY SET UP, AS YOU
CAN SEE, CAMERAS STANDING BY AND
JUST WAITING FOR THEM TO ARRIVE
AND, OF COURSE, WE'LL TAKE THAT
PRESS CONFERENCE FOR YOU LIVE
WHEN IT HAPPENS.
FIRST RIGHT TO HOWARD KURTZ AND
"RELIABLE SOURCES" FOR A
CRITICAL LOOK AT HOW THE NEWS
MEDIA HAS BEEN COVERING THE
EVENTS HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
WOLF BLITZER, AS WELL.
HE'S BEEN HERE REPORTING ON
THIS, THE VERY LATEST ON WHAT WE
LEARNED ABOUT THIS STORY.
WOLF?
>> HOWIE GOING TO BE JOINING US
IN A LITTLE WHILE, SOLEDAD.
EXPECTING AS YOU POINTED OUT THE
NEWS CONFERENCE TO BEGIN
MOMENTARILY.
THEY'RE GETTING READY FOR THAT.
AMONG OTHER THINGS, WE EXPECT TO
LEARN THE RESULTS OF THE
AUTOPSIES, AS YOU SAY, WERE
PERFORMED ON THE BODIES OF THE
GUNMAN AND HIS MOTHER.
ALREADY THIS MORNING WE LEARNED
A HORRIFYING NEW DETAILS ABOUT
FRIDAY'S SCHOOL MASSACRE.
THE GUNMAN USED HIS ASSAULT
WEAPON LITERALLY TO SHOOT HIS
OWN ENTRY WAY INTO THE SCHOOL
BUILDING.
CONNECTICUT'S MEDICAL EXAMINER
SAID THE SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE
FOUND AT THE SCENE WAS THE
PRIMARY WEAPON USED IN THIS
MASSACRE.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI REPORTS THAT
INVESTIGATORS ARE NOW TRYING TO
PIECE TOGETHER THE GUNMAN'S
ACTIONS IN THE DAYS BEFORE THE
SHOOTINGS.
LOOKING AT SURVEILLANCE VIDEO
FROM PLACES HE MAY HAVE VISITED.
ALL OF THIS UNFOLDING, EVEN AS
WE SPEAK RIGHT NOW.
MEANWHILE, THE CONNECTICUT
GOVERNOR DAN MALLOY A FAMILIAR
FACE.
THIS MORNING, HE SPOKE TO OUR
OWN CANDY CROWLEY ON CNN'S
"STATE OF THE UNION."
CANDY JOINING US WITH MORE ON
THAT.
CANDY?
>> WOLF, THE GOVERNOR DID SAY,
IN FACT, THAT THE SHOOTER DID
BLAST HIS WAY INTO THAT
BUILDING, AS WE KNOW, BY NOW.
THERE WAS A BELL.
YOU HAD TO BE RUNG INTO THE
BUILDING FROM THE INSIDE.
BUT HE, INSTEAD, USED THAT
SEMIAUTOMATIC TO BLAST HIS WAY
INTO THE BUILDING.
HE ALSO TALKED ABOUT HOW
INVESTIGATORS ARE LOOKING AT HOW
THESE GUNS ARE PURCHASED.
THEY KNOW THEY WERE PURCHASED BY
THE MOTHER.
HE MENTIONED THAT -- DID SHE
ALLOW HER SON USE OF THEM EVEN
PRIOR TO THE DAY HE TOOK THEM
AND WENT INTO THAT ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
BUT THERE'S ALSO VERY PERSONAL
SIDE OF THIS INTERVIEW AND SAW
THE GOVERNOR VERY MUCH WITH
TEARS HIS EYES WHEN I ASKED HIM
ABOUT THAT TIME WHEN HE HAD TO
TELL THOSE PARENTS GATHERED AT
THE FIREHOUSE NEAR THE BUILDING
THAT THEIR CHILDREN WERE GONE
AND WOULD NOT BE COMING BACK.
TAKE A LISTEN TO THIS EXCHANGE.
>> CANDY, I WAS WITH THE VAST
MAJORITY OF THE FAMILIES FRIDAY
MORNING AND, ULTIMATELY, I HAD
TO BREAK IT TO ALL THE FOLKS
THAT WERE ASSEMBLED AT THE
FIREHOUSE THAT THEIR CHILDREN OR
THEIR LOVED ONE, IN THE CASE OF
THE ADULTS, WERE NOT COMING
HOME.
AND THAT'S AN EXERCISE THAT I
WILL LIVE WITH FOR THE REST OF
MY LIFE.
IT'S NOT SOMETHING YOU'RE
PREPARED FOR AND, YOU KNOW, GO
ON.
BUT, LISTEN, I'M THE GOVERNOR OF
THE STATE OF CONNECTICUT, WE
HAVE A JOB TO DO.
WE HAVE TO PROTECT PEOPLE, WE
HAVE TO HELP PEOPLE RECOVER, WE
HAVE TO MOVE ON AND GET CHILDREN
BACK TO SCHOOL AS QUICKLY AS
POSSIBLE IN THE BROADER SYSTEM.
AND HOPEFULLY THESE CHILDREN, AT
THIS SCHOOL, BACK TO SCHOOL, A
SCHOOL AS QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE.
>> MAKE SURE I UNDERSTOOD YOU
CORRE
CORRECTLY.
YOU HAD TO TELL THE FAMILIES IN
THAT ROOM THAT SOME FEARED OR
HAD KNOWN AT A GUT LEVEL, YOU
WERE THE ONE THAT FINALIZED FOR
THEM.
>> YES.
>> TELL ME ABOUT THAT MOMENT.
>> IT'S A VERY DIFFICULT THING
TO DO.
THESE PARENTS HAD BEEN GATHERED
FOR A NUMBER OF HOURS CLINGING
TO HOPE.
NEWS REPORTS WERE SWIRLING
AROUND THEM OUTSIDE THE
BUILDING.
AND SOMEONE HAD TO DECIDE HOW TO
HANDLE THAT SITUATION.
AND, UTIMALTIMATELY, IT FELL UPE
TO DO THAT.
YOU COULD NEVER BE PREPARED TO
TELL 18 OR 20 FOLKS OR,
ACTUALLY, FAMILIES, THAT THEIR
LOVED ONE WOULD NOT BE RETURNING
TO THEM THAT DAY OR IN THE
FUTURE IS A TOUGH ASSIGNMENT.
>> SO, YOU HEARD THE GOVERNOR
THERE, WOLF, TALK ABOUT.
YOU KNOW, IT'S SOMETHING YOU
LIVE WITH AND SO MUCH TALK NOW
IS GOING TO BE ABOUT MOVING ON
AND MOVING THROUGH THE GRIEF.
AND THE FACT IS, WE ALL KNOW
THESE FAMILIES WILL NEVER BE THE
SAME AND NEITHER WILL THOSE WHO
HAVE BEEN CLOSEST TO THIS,
INCLUDING THE GOVERNOR.
WE TALKED LATER IN THE HOUR TO
JIM HICKEN LOOPER WHO WAS THE
GOVERNOR OF COLORADO AND WAS
THERE FOR THE AURORA SHOOTING
EARLIER THIS YEAR AND HE TALKED
ABOUT HOW HE ALMOST BECAME
FRIENDS WITH THOSE FAMILIES
BECAUSE YOU HAVE TO BE THERE FOR
THE MOST DIFFICULT TIME IN THEIR
LIFE AND THAT'S DEFINITELY HOW
THE CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR FEELS,
WOLF.
>> SO HARD, SO PAINFUL.
BUT THEY'RE THE GOVERNORS AND
THAT'S WHAT THEY HAVE TO DO IN A
SITUATION, A HORRIFYING
SITUATION LIKE THIS.
CANDY IS GOING TO BE BACK AT THE
TOP OF THE HOUR WITH "STATE OF
THE UNION."
WE'LL SEE YOU THEN.
>>> MEANWHILE, CNN IS MAKING IT
POSSIBLE TO HELP THE FAMILIES OF
THE VICTIMS IN CONNECTICUT, YOU
CAN IMPACT YOUR WORLD.
IT'S AVAILABLE BY GOING TO
CNN.COM/IMPACT.
>>> AFTER THE BREAK, SOLEDAD AND
I WILL SPEAK WITH HOWARD KURTZ
OF CNN'S "RELIABLE SOURCES"
ABOUT THE EXPERIENCE OF COVERING
TRAGEDY LIKE THIS.
♪ OOH BABY, LOOKS LIKE
YOU NEED A LITTLE HELP THERE ♪
♪ OOH BABY,
CAN I DO FOR YOU TODAY? ♪
[ Female Announcer ] NEED HELP
KEEPING YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE?
ALIGN CAN HELP.
ONLY ALIGN HAS BIFANTIS,
A PATENTED PROBIOTIC
THAT NATURALLY HELPS MAINTAIN
YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE.
TRY ALIGN TO HELP RETAIN
A BALANCED DIGESTIVE SYSTEM.
TRY THE #1 GASTROENTEROLOGIST
RECOMMENDED PROBIOTIC.
ALIGN.
A REGULAR GUY
WITH AN IRREGULAR HEARTBEAT.
THE USUAL, BOB?
NOT TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
BOB HAS AFIB:
ATRIAL FIBRILLATION NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
A CONDITION THAT PUTS HIM
AT GREATER RISK FOR A STROKE.
[ GPS ] TURN LEFT.
I DON'T THINK SO.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR YEARS, BOB TOOK WARFARIN,
AND MADE A MONTHLY TRIP TO THE
CLINIC TO GET HIS BLOOD TESTED.
BUT NOT ANYMORE.
BOB'S DOCTOR RECOMMENDED
A DIFFERENT OPTION:
ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
XARELTO® IS THE FIRST AND ONLY
ONCE-A-DAY PRESCRIPTION
BLOOD THINNER
FOR PATIENTS WITH AFIB
NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
THAT DOESN'T REQUIRE
ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING.
LIKE WARFARIN,
XARELTO® IS PROVEN EFFECTIVE
TO REDUCE THE RISK
OF AN AFIB-RELATED STROKE.
THERE IS LIMITED DATA
ON HOW THESE DRUGS COMPARE
WHEN WARFARIN IS WELL MANAGED.
NO ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING
MEANS BOB CAN SPEND HIS
EXTRA TIME HOWEVER HE LIKES.
NEW ZEALAND!
XARELTO®
IS JUST ONE PILL A DAY,
TAKEN WITH THE EVENING MEAL.
AND WITH
NO DIETARY RESTRICTIONS,
BOB CAN EAT THE HEALTHY FOODS
HE LIKES.
DO NOT STOP TAKING
XARELTO® RIVAROXABAN
WITHOUT TALKING TO THE DOCTOR
WHO PRESCRIBES IT FOR YOU.
STOPPING MAY INCREASE YOUR RISK
OF HAVING A STROKE.
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU DEVELOP ANY SIGNS
OR SYMPTOMS OF BLEEDING,
LIKE UNUSUAL BRUISING
OR TINGLING.
YOU MAY HAVE A HIGHER RISK
OF BLEEDING
IF YOU TAKE XARELTO®
WITH ASPIRIN PRODUCTS,
NSAIDS OR BLOOD THINNERS.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE TAKING XARELTO®
IF YOU CURRENTLY HAVE
ABNORMAL BLEEDING.
XARELTO® CAN CAUSE BLEEDING,
WHICH CAN BE SERIOUS,
AND RARELY MAY LEAD TO DEATH.
YOU ARE LIKELY TO BRUISE
MORE EASILY ON XARELTO®,
AND IT MAY TAKE LONGER
FOR BLEEDING TO STOP.
TELL YOUR DOCTORS
YOU ARE TAKING XARELTO®
BEFORE ANY PLANNED MEDICAL
OR DENTAL PROCEDURES.
BEFORE STARTING XARELTO®,
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ANY CONDITIONS,
SUCH AS KIDNEY, LIVER
OR BLEEDING PROBLEMS.
READY TO CHANGE YOUR ROUTINE?
ASK YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
FOR MORE INFORMATION
INCLUDING COST SUPPORT OPTIONS,
CALL 1-888-XARELTO
OR VISIT GOXARELTO.COM.
>>> WELCOME BACK.
WE'RE STANDING BY FOR A NEWS
CONFERENCE.
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE.
YOU SEE THE MICROPHONES THERE.
THEY'RE GETTING READY TO BRIEF
US ON THE LATEST ON THIS
INVESTIGATION.
THIS HORRIBLE, HORRIBLE DISASTER
THAT HAPPENED IN THIS SMALL TOWN
HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
SOLEDAD O'BRIEN IS JOINING US.
HOWARD KURTZ IS ALSO JOINING US
NOW FROM CNN'S "RELIABLE
SOURCES" IN WASHINGTON, D.C.
HOWIE, A TREMENDOUS, ENORMOUS
AMOUNT OF MEDIA PRESENCE HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
WHAT IS YOUR IMPRESSION OF HOW
THIS STORY UNFOLDED IN THE NEWS
SO FAR?
>> WOLF, UNLIKE ANY TRAGEDY THAT
WE HAVE COLLECTIVELY LIVED
THROUGH, THIS ONE HAS SEAR UNDER
TO AMERICA'S SOUL.
EVERYONE IS TALKING ABOUT,
EVERYONE IS CONSUMED ABOUT IT
AND EVERY ONLINE CONVERSATION ON
SOCIAL MEDIA SITES IS ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED IN NEWTOWN.
I HAVE TO TELL YOU FOR ALL OF
THE COVERAGE THERE FOR YOU AND
OTHERS, THERE ARE TIMES WHEN I
HAVE TO TURN OFF THE TV AND
OTHER JOURNALISTS TOLD ME THIS
BEFORE.
THE FEELINGS ARE SO RAW IT IS
HARD TO WATCH.
JOURNALISTS ARE TRAINED TO BE
OBJECTIVE, BUT HOW CAN ANY HUMAN
BEING BE DISPASSIONATE ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED THERE.
>> HOWIE, I'LL ANSWER THAT FOR
YOU, IF I CAN.
>> GO AHEAD, SOLEDAD.
>> I WAS GOING TO SAY THE SAME
THING THAT WOLF WAS GOING TO
SAY.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU CAN HAVE NO
COMPASSION OR BEING PASSIONATE
ABOUT IT.
SORT OF FOCUSING ON DOING A JOB.
I LOOK AT ALL THE LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS HERE.
I CAN'T EVEN IMAGINE WHAT
THEY'VE BEEN THROUGH.
MANY TALKING ABOUT CARRYING
CHILDREN, YOU KNOW, OUT OF THAT
SCHOOL.
I GUESS, FOR ME, I THINK WE TRY
TO FOCUS ON JUST GETTING
INFORMATION OUT AND EVEN IF YOU
HAVE TO INTERVIEW GRIEVING
PARENTS OR PARENTS WHO ARE
GRIEVING, BUT RELIEVED BECAUSE
THEIR CHILDREN HAVE SURVIVED BUT
GRIEVING FOR THE COMMUNITY.
I THINK YOU JUST FOCUS ON TRYING
TO ASK THE QUESTIONS THAT NEED
TO BE ASKED IN THOUGHTFUL AND IN
A COMPASSIONATE WAY.
>> RIGHT, SOLEDAD, JOURNALISTS
ARE TRAINED TO DO THEIR JOBS
EVEN IN MOST AWFUL CIRCUMSTANCES
LIKE THIS.
YOU GET THE CALL, RUN OUT TO
NEWTOWN, WHAT IS THE EMOTIONAL
IMPACT ON YOU OR DO YOU HAVE TO
PUT THAT ASIDE WHILE YOU'RE
DOING THE JOB OF A
CORRESPONDENT?
>> YEAH, YOU KNOW, I DON'T EVEN
THINK ABOUT IT, HONESTLY.
I HAVEN'T TALKED TO MY CHILDREN.
MY DAUGHTER, I CALLED HER LAST
NIGHT AND THAT IS THE FIRST TIME
I TALKED TO THE KIDS.
I LET MY HUSBAND DEAL WITH THAT.
MY DAUGHTER SAID TO ME, I SAID,
HOW ARE YOU?
SHE SAID, MOM, HOW ARE YOU?
I SO APPRECIATED THAT AND I
THINK THAT'S WHAT A LOT OF
PEOPLE IN THIS COMMUNITY ARE
FEELING.
SO MANY PEOPLE ARE JUST WORRIED
ABOUT THEM.
I WON'T EVEN THINK ABOUT IT
UNTIL I'M HOME IN A COUPLE WEEKS
FROM NOW.
RIGHT NOW WE HAVE A JOB TO DO
AND THAT JOB IS AS WE'RE WAITING
FOR THIS PRESS CONFERENCE TO GET
THE MOST INFORMATION WE CAN FROM
THE LAW ENFORCEMENT, MEDICAL
EXAMINER AND PIECE TOGETHER THIS
STORY BECAUSE THAT'S WHAT PEOPLE
ARE INTERESTED IN TRYING TO FIND
OUT WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
>> WOLF, DO YOU HAVE ANY FEELING
AS THIS WHOLE TOWN IS IN A STATE
OF GRIEF THAT BECAUSE WE COME
WITH A BIG FOOTPRINT AND THE
CAMERA CREWS THAT PERHAPS WE
COLLECTIVELY ARE INTRUDING AT A
VERY, AT THE WORST MOMENT OF
THESE PEOPLE'S LIVES?
>> YOU KNOW, I'VE BEEN HERE NOW
ALL DAY YESTERDAY, ALL DAY
TODAY.
GOT HERE LATE, LATE FRIDAY NIGHT
FROM WASHINGTON.
AND THERE HAVE BEEN A FEW, I CAN
COUNT THEM REALLY ON ONE HAND A
FEW PEOPLE HAVE SAID TO ME, GET
OUT.
LEAVE US ALONE.
STUFF LIKE THAT.
BUT OVERWHELMINGLY, HOWIE, MOST
OF THE PEOPLE HERE IN NEWTOWN IN
DANBURY AND ELSE WHERE IN
CONNECTICUT, THEY HAVE BEEN
VERY, VERY GRATEFUL BECAUSE THEY
WANT THIS, THE WORLD TO
UNDERSTAND WHAT THEY ARE GOING
THROUGH RIGHT NOW HERE IN
CONNECTICUT.
OVERWHELMINGLY, THE PEOPLE, SURE
THERE'S A HUGE MEDIA FOOTPRINT
IN NEWTOWN RIGHT NOW, BUT I
THINK THE FOLKS UNDERSTAND THAT
WE HAVE A JOB TO DO AND THEY
WANT THE WORLD TO SEE WHAT'S
GOING ON.
IT'S NOT JUST HERE IN
CONNECTICUT OR THE UNITED STATES
EVEN.
WE'RE BEING SEEN AROUND THE
WORLD --
>> AROUND THE WORLD.
>> PEOPLE ARE REACHING OUT,
PEOPLE ARE APPRECIATIVE OF
WHAT'S GOING ON AND WE'RE TRYING
TO BRING THAT STORY AND MAYBE WE
WILL LEARN SOME LESSONS.
MAYBE I'M OVERLY OPTIMISTIC.
PREVENT THIS KIND OF DISASTER
DOWN THE ROAD.
>> I THINK TELEVISION CAN HELP
WITH THE HEALING PROCESS AT A
MOMENT WHEN WE HAVE THE NATION'S
ATTENTION TRANFIXED ON THE TOWN
THAT YOU'RE IN.
WOLF?
>> HOWIE, ALL RIGHT, STAND BY.
I WANT EVERYONE TO STAND BY.
SOLEDAD IS GOING TO BE WITH US,
WE'RE GOING TO CONTINUE OUR
COVERAGE.
WE'RE WAITING, WE'RE WAITING FOR
THIS NEWS CONFERENCE TO TAKE
PLACE.
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE ARE
GETTING READY TO BRIEF US ON THE
LATEST INFORMATION THAT THEY
HAVE FROM THIS INVESTIGATION.
WE'LL HAVE LIVE COVERAGE OF THAT
MORE WITH HOWIE AND SOLEDAD,
WHEN WE COME BACK.
[ Male Announcer ] When Ziggy
the cat appeared at their door,
he opened up
Jake's very private world.
At first, Jake's family
thought they saved Ziggy,
but his connection with Jake
has been a lifesaver.
For a love this strong,
his family only feeds him Iams.
Compared to other
leading brands,
it has 50% more
animal protein...
...to help keep Ziggy's body
as strong as a love
that reaches further
than anyone's words.
Iams. Keep Love Strong.
CAN YOUR MOISTURIZER DO THAT?
[ Female Announcer ]
DERMATOLOGIST RECOMMENDED
Aveeno HAS AN OAT FORMULA,
NOW PROVEN
TO BUILD A MOISTURE RESERVE,
SO SKIN CAN REPLENISH ITSELF.
THAT'S HEALTHY SKIN FOR LIFE.
ONLY FROM Aveeno.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
HOW THEY'LL LIVE TOMORROW.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
I NEED YOU.
I FEEL SO ALONE.
BUT YOU'RE NOT
ALONE.
I KNEW YOU'D COME.
LIKE I COULD STAY AWAY.
YOU KNOW I CAN'T DO THIS
WITHOUT YOU.
YOU'LL NEVER HAVE TO.
YOU'RE ALWAYS THERE
FOR ME.
SHH!
I'LL GET YOU
A RENTAL CAR.
I COULD ALSO USE
AN UMBRELLA.
FALL IN LOVE WITH
PROGRESSIVE'S CLAIMS SERVICE.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
YOU'RE TAKING A LOOK AT THE
MAKINGS OF A PRESS CONFERENCE.
YOU CAN SEE THERE, THERE ARE
ROUGHLY TWO DOZEN CAMERA SET UP
AND WE'RE WAITING FOR THE STATE
POLICE, LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE
HAS BEEN UPDATING US IN THESE
PRESS CONFERENCES.
HE IS GOING TO BE JOINED THIS
MORNING BY THE MEDICAL EXAMINER
OF THE STATE OF CONNECTICUT,
WAIN CARVER.
WHERE THE INVESTIGATION STANDS
AND THEY ARE NOW FOCUSING ON
BALLISTICS AND WEAPONS AND THEY
SAID THAT THEY'LL BE ABLE TO
ANSWER A LOT OF THE QUESTIONS
THAT WE HAD OVER THE LAST COUPLE
DAYS THAT HAVE GONE UNANSWERED.
ALSO THE MEDICAL EXAMINER HAS
WRAPPED UP HIS AUTOPSY OF THE
SHOOTER AND THE SHOOTER'S
MOTHER.
HE SAID THAT WOULD BE DONE THIS
MORNING AND WE ARE EXPECTING HE
WILL GIVE US SOME INFORMATION
ABOUT ANY INFORMATION THAT THEY
HAVE BEEN ABLE TO DETERMINE OUT
OF THAT.
THAT'S THE PRESS CONFERENCE
WE'RE WAITING FOR AND WE'LL
BRING THAT TO YOU LIVE WHEN THAT
HAPPENS.
RIGHT NOW WE WANT TO GET TO
HOWIE CURTS FROM "RELIABLE
SOURCES" FOR
HOWIE?
>> THE JOURNALISTS ARE FACING
MANY CHALLENGES, NO MORE
DAUNTING THAN IN THE FIRST FEW
HOURS AS SOME RANGE FROM
INCOMPLETE TO JUST PLAIN WRONG.
>> THIS MAY HAVE BEEN, MAY HAVE
BEEN THE FATHER OF A STUDENT.
>> THE SHOOTER HAS BEEN
IDENTIFIED TO ME BY A SOURCE AS
RYAN LANZA.
RYAN LANZA IN HIS 20s.
APPARENTLY WE'RE TOLD FROM THE
SOURCE FROM THIS AREA.
>> WE HAVE JUST NOW CONFIRMED
THE SHOOTER IS IDENTIFIED.
HE IS 20-YEAR-OLD RYAN LANZA.
>> IT MAY TURN OUT AT THE END OF
THE DAY THE PERSON WHO FIRED THE
SHOTS WAS RYAN LANZA'S BROTHER,
ADAM.
>> CONTRARY TO CONFLICTING
INFORMATION THAT THEY HAD PASSED
ON, WE CAN NOW TELL YOU
ACCORDING TO SEVERAL SOURCES
THAT THE NAME OF THE SHOOTER IN
THIS CASE IS ADAM LANZA.
>> JOINING US NOW TO EXAMINE THE
COVERAGE OF WHAT UNFOLDED IN
CONNECTICUT.
LAUREN ASHBURN EDITOR AND CHIEF
OF DAILY DOWNLOAD.COM AND FRANK
SESNO AND A FORMER CNN
WASHINGTON BUREAU CHIEF.
FRANK, YOU HAVE BEEN HERE WHEN
TRAGEDY ERUPTED AND YOU HAD TO
GO ON THE AIR WHEN INFORMATION
IS HARD TO COME BY.
WHY IS IT SO HARD WHEN THE
BROTHER WAS INACCURATELY
IDENTIFIED TO KEEP THAT
INFORMATION OFF THE AIR?
>> IT'S WHAT I CALL THE LANGUAGE
OF LIVE.
WE REPORT SOMETHING AS IT'S
HAPPENING AND QUITE OFTEN YOU'RE
FOLLOWING LAW ENFORCEMENT OR
ANYBODY ELSE DOWN THE WRONG PATH
OR DEAD END INFORMATION.
WHY IT WAS SO IMPORTANT WHEN YOU
HEARD THERE SUSAN CANDIOTTI TOLD
US SOURCES ARE BUILDING INTO THE
LANGUAGE THAT JOURNALISTS USE
THIS LANGUAGE OF UNCERTAINTY
BECAUSE THINGS DO CHANGE.
>> BUT LAW ENFORCEMENT SOURCES
SOMETIMES PROVIDE INFORMATION
THAT TURNS OUT TO BE WRONG.
THIS IS A CLASSIC EXAMPLE, LAURA
ASHBURN.
HOW OFTEN ARE JOURNALISTS'
CREDIBILITY.
>> HOW COULD YOU WRONGLY
IDENTIFY THE VICTIM, BUT, NOW, I
THINK PEOPLE BELIEVE THAT THIS
IS THE WAY JOURNALISM IS.
THEY'RE GOING TO GET IT WRONG
AND YOU DON'T ALWAYS HAVE TO
BELIEVE EVERYTHING THAT A
JOURNALIST TELLS YOU AND I THINK
THAT'S SAD.
>> I DON'T KNOW, I WROTE A
COLUMN REALLY CRITICAL OF THIS.
THIS GUY WAS IDENTIFIED FOR
HOURS.
NO ONE WENT TO TRY TO
INDEPENDENTLY VERIFY THE LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIAL DID.
>> YOU ACCEPT THE NOTION BECAUSE
SOMEBODY REPORTED IT AND THEN IT
CHANGES BECAUSE THIS IS A MOVING
STORY THIS IS JUST THE WAY IT
IS.
CAN WE DO BETTER?
>> OF COURSE WE CAN DO BETTER.
IN ONE PART, I AGREE WITH LAUREN
ABOUT PEOPLE ACCEPTING THIS MORE
BECAUSE OF ALL THE PROLIFERATION
OF NEW KINDS OF MEDIA.
BUT, HOWIE, IT'S AWFUL.
YOU KNOW, THEY PUT RYAN LANZA'S
PICTURE OUT THERE AND IT WAS
SHARED ON FACEBOOK 1,000 TIMES
IN A MINUTE.
IT'S A NIGHTMARE.
THIS GUY IS SITTING ON A BUS
IDENTIFIED AS A MASS MUFRDERER
FOR HOURS.
SLATE SAID LOOK LIKE THAT
FACEBOOK PAGE OF RYAN LANZA WE
LINKED TO WAS INCORRECT.
>> GEE.
>> THANKS.
>> NO, LOOKS LIKE -- IT'S EITHER
INCORRECT, FRANK, OR IT'S NOT.
THIS LACK OF PRECISION IN
JOURNALISM IS WRONG.
>> WHEN STUFF IS HAPPENING AS
FAST AS IT HAPPENS HERE AND YOU
LIVE IN THE INSTANT INFORMATION
WORLD, THIS STUFF WILL HAPPEN.
IT CAN BE FOR DAYS, COME ON.
>> THEY'RE GOING TO GET THE
WRONG PERSON AND IDENTIFY HIM AS
A MASS MURDERER.
>> WHAT I'M SAYING IS THAT
INFORMATION, RIGHT OR WRONG,
TRAVELS MUCH FASTER THAN
COOPERATION SOMETIMES.
AND THE FACT OF THE MATTER IS
THAT THE SUSPECT WAS CARRYING A
BAD I.D., THAT INFORMATION CAME
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT.
LAW ENFORCEMENT WAS THE ONLY
FORM OF INFORMATION THAT THE
MEDIA HAD AT THE TIME.
>> WHY?
>> THEY'RE NOT GOING TO BE ABLE
TO GO INTO THE SCHOOL --
>> POST IT ON FACEBOOK WHO THEY
SAID WAS DEAD.
THAT WAS A SOURCE OF
INFORMATION.
>> IT'S HAPPENING IN REAL-TIME.
THE FOG OF WAR ON THE
BATTLEFIELD.
>> THAT'S A NICE TERM.
>> LET ME JUMP IN.
A LOT OF EMOTION HERE AT THIS
TABLE.
LAUREN, WHEN YOU WATCHED THE
COVERAGE, ADMITTEDLY, IT'S HARD
TO WATCH.
SEE ANCHORS AND CORRESPONDENTS
HAVING TO DEAL WITH THIS
UNSPEAKABLE TRAGEDY, IT SEEMS
LIKE THEY'RE TRYING TO KEEP
THEIR EMOTIONS OUT OF IT,
DOESN'T IT?
>> OF COURSE.
WHEN I COVERED 9/1 1, THAT'S
EXACTLY WHAT I DID.
I HAD THE PICTURE OF THE
PENTAGON BEHIND ME AND SMOKE
COMING UP AND YOU CAN'T THINK
ABOUT IT, AS SOLEDAD O'BRIEN
SAID EARLIER.
YOU CAN'T CALL YOUR CHILDREN,
YOU CAN'T GET INTO THAT
EMOTIONAL MINDSET.
HOWEVER, LOOKING AT IT YESTERDAY
FROM MY KITCHEN TABLE WHERE I
WAS WRITING CHRISTMAS CARDS IN
FRONT OF A FIRE, I COULDN'T HELP
BUT REALIZE THE DISPASSION THAT
THE JOURNALISTS DID HAVE AND I
QUESTION IN "THE DAILY BEAST"
PIECE THAT I WROTE WHETHER OR
NOT WE COULDN'T DO A LITTLE BIT
BETTER.
MAYBE IT WOULD SERVE THE
AUDIENCE A LITTLE BIT MORE TO
INJECT A LITTLE BIT OF EMOTION.
I'M NOT SAYING LET'S START
CRYING AND DOING ALL OF THAT.
>> IT'S HUMANITY.
>> THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE TALKING
ABOUT.
IT'S HUMANITY.
>> I NEED TO KNOW, I NEED TO SEE
THAT IT IS AFFECTING THEM THE
WAY IT IS AFFECTING THE PEOPLE
AT HOME.
>> LET ME ASK YOU A RELATED
QUESTION WHICH WE'VE SEEN FROM
MANY OF THE NETWORKS, INTERVIEWS
WITH SOME OF THE YOUNG
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL CHILDREN AND
BASICALLY EYEWITNESSES TO WHAT
HAPPENED.
SOMETIMES THEY WERE ACCOMPANIED
BY PARENTS.
CNN POLICY PARENTS HAVE TO GIVE
PERMISSION.
>> I DO NOT WANT TO SEE IT.
I DO NOT WANT TO SEE IT.
LOOK.
YOU MAKE THAT DECISION ON A
CASE-BY-CASE BASIS BUT TO HAVE
AN 8-YEAR-OLD OR 6-YEAR-OLD
DESCRIBE THIS SCENE, I FEEL LIKE
IT'S LUDICROUS TO PUT THAT ON
TELEVISION.
GET AN ADULT.
YOU KNOW, LEAVE THAT POOR CHILD
ALONE.
>> WHAT ABOUT THE WHOLE QUESTION
OF, STARTING TO HEAR RUMBLINGS
ABOUT A GUN CONTROL DEBATE.
YOU HAVE THE PARTISANS COME ON
AND THEY TAKE THEIR SHOT.
IT'S THE FAULT OF GUNS, IT'S NOT
THE FAULT OF GUNS.
WHEN IT COMES TO STRAIGHT
REPORTING, CONGRESS IS NOT GOING
TO ACT IN THIS, EVEN DEMOCRATS
DON'T WANT TO DO IT.
EVEN PRESIDENT OBAMA SHIED AWAY
FROM IT.
ARE THE MEDIA SHYING AWAY FROM,
AS THEY HAVE IN THE PAST, A
REAL, HONEST, CANDID DEBATE
ABOUT GUNS IN THIS COUNTRY?
>> RIGHT NOW, NO.
RIGHT NOW, ALL THE FOCUS --
>> A WEEK FROM NOW?
>> THAT'S THE QUESTION.
THAT'S WHY I THINK THERE NEEDS
TO BE A REAL MEDIA AGENDA HERE.
NOT A MEDIA AGENDA TO TAKE
SIDES, BUT KEEP A VERY SENSITIVE
IN THE --
>> THE MEDIA DID PUT --
>> TED KOPPEL HAD "NIGHTLINE"
BUILT AROUND THE HOSTAGE CRISIS.
MUCH OF THE VIOLENCE THAT
RESULTS FROM GUNS ARE GUNS
PURBFECTLY LEGALLY OBTAINED.
WHAT DO WE KNOW?
WHERE DOES IT COME FROM?
ALL SIDES OF THE DEBATE.
GREAT PIECE IN "THE ATLANTIC"
THE CASE FOR ALL GUNS.
COME AT THIS, THE MEDIA NEED TO
COME ON THIS ON A SUSTAINED
BASIS PUTTING THE FACTS IN THERE
AND PUTTING THE DIFFICULT ISSUE
IN FRONT OF THE AMERICAN PEOPLE
SO THAT WE CAN HAVE A GROWN-UP
CONVERSATION.
>> THEY WON'T.
>> WHY?
>> BECAUSE WE MOVE ON TO THE
NEXT THING.
>> I AM SAYING WE SHOULDN'T.
>> I AGREE WITH YOU 100%, BUT WE
WILL.
>> AND I AGREE WITH BOTH OF YOU,
AS WELL.
LAUREN IS RIGHT.
THE PROBLEM WITH THIS, HOWIE, ON
MSNBC I SAW FRIDAY AFTERNOON,
THEY WERE ALREADY IN TALKING
ABOUT, I HOPE WE HAVE THE
POLITICAL CAPITAL NOW TO
CHANGE -- THAT'S NOT THE TIME ON
FRIDAY, SATURDAY AND SUNDAY.
NO, I TOTALLY --
>> WHY DO YOU DISAGREE?
>> I DISAGREE, BECAUSE WHEN ELSE
ARE YOU GOING TO HAVE IT?
THIS IS THE MOMENT WHEN YOU HAVE
PEOPLE WHO ARE EMOTIONALLY
DISTRAUGHT LOOKING FOR OR
INTERESTED.
>> THEY ARE EMOTIONALLY
DISTRAUGHT AND IF YOU'RE GOING
TO HAVE A SERIOUS CASE WITH
ATTENTION SPAN, YOU'RE GOING TO
HAVE TO DO OVER TIME AND WHEN
THEY'RE NOT EMOTIONAL.
>> WE DON'T DO IT.
>> THAT'S WHAT I'M SAYING.
WE IN THE MEDIA HAVE A JOB, TO
GIVE VOICE TO THE VOICELESS.
NO ONE MORE VOICELESS THAN A 6,
7, 14, 16 OR 18-YEAR-OLD KID WHO
HAS HAD THEIR LIFE TAKEN AWAY.
>> FRANK, ALSO BEYOND THE MEDIA,
I THINK THE ACADEMIC WORLD THAT
YOU'RE PART OF CAN PLAY A REALLY
IMPORTANT ROLE IN THIS IN TERMS
OF FRAMING IT AND PUSHING IT AND
HAVING FORUMS AND THE PEOPLE WHO
FUND THESE KINDS OF THINGS.
PEOPLE SHOULD TRY TO HAVE THIS
KIND OF --
>> CAN I SAY ONE THING, HOWIE,
THAT IS REALLY IMPORTANT.
WHEN I TALK ABOUT THIS AGENDA,
I'M NOT TALKING ABOUT THE
MEDIA --
>> I THINK THE MEDIA SHY AWAY
FROM THIS BECAUSE THERE IS A
FEAR OF ALIENATING A BROAD SWATH
OF THE LEADERSHIP AND VIEWERSHIP
WHO MAY DISAGREE ON EITHER SIDE
OF THIS VOLATILE ISSUE BUT I
AGREE --
>> IF YOU LOOK AT THIS AS A
PUBLIC HEALTH EMERGENCY, YOU GO
FOR THE DATA.
>> WE HAVE TO HAVE THE DEBATE
WHEN PEOPLE ARE THINKING ABOUT
GUN CONTROL BECAUSE IN A WEEK
THEY'RE GOING TO BE THINKING
ABOUT SOME OTHER TRAGEDY.
SOME VOLCANO ERUPTING OR BUS
CRASH -- THE FISCAL CLIFF.
AND THEY'RE NOT GOING TO BE
THINKING ABOUT GUN CONTROL.
DO IT NOW.
>> IT'S NOT JUST ABOUT GUN
CONTROL, FIRST OF ALL.
LET ME SAY THAT.
IT IS ABOUT THE GUN ISSUE, THE
MENTAL HEALTH ISSUE AND THE
ACCESS ISSUE.
>> FASCINATING DEBATE THAT I
HOPE CONTINUES NOT JUST HERE BUT
ELSE WHERE.
THANKS VERY MUCH.
>>> NEXT, WE'LL GO BACK TO
CONNECTICUT WITH WOLF BLITZER
AND DR. SANJAY GUPTA FOR MORE
COVERAGE OF THIS TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT.
[ Female Announcer ]
IMAGINE SKIN SO HEALTHY,
IT NEVER GETS DRY AGAIN.
CAN YOUR MOISTURIZER DO THAT?
[ Female Announcer ]
DERMATOLOGIST RECOMMENDED
Aveeno HAS AN OAT FORMULA,
NOW PROVEN
TO BUILD A MOISTURE RESERVE,
SO SKIN CAN REPLENISH ITSELF.
THAT'S HEALTHY SKIN FOR LIFE.
ONLY FROM Aveeno.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
JILL AND HER MOUTH HAVE LIVED
A GREAT LIFE.
BUT SHE HAS SOME DENTAL ISSUES
SHE'S NOT HAPPY ABOUT.
SO I INTRODUCED JILL
TO CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SELECTED FOR PEOPLE OVER 50.
PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE IS A
TOOTHPASTE THAT DEFENDS AGAINST
TENDER, INFLAMED GUMS,
SENSITIVITY AND WEAK ENAMEL.
CONDITIONS PEOPLE OVER 50
EXPERIENCE.
CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SO JILL CAN KEEP LIVING
THE GOOD LIFE.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
>>> SO SAD.
PEOPLE ARE EMOTIONAL,
UNDERSTANDABLY, HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THEY'RE WALKING PAST THESE
MEMORIALS AND JUST REFLECTING ON
WHAT IS GOING ON.
SO MANY QUESTIONS REMAIN
UNANSWERED.
WE MIGHT GET SOME ANSWERS AT A
NEWS CONFERENCE.
WE'RE AWAITING THE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE, THEY'RE GOING TO
BE SPEAKING SHORTLY, WE'RE TOLD.
WE'VE BEEN EXPECTING THEM FOR A
WHILE.
YOU SEE THE MICROPHONES ARE ALL
SET UP.
WE'LL HAVE LIVE COVERAGE ONCE
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
SHOW UP THERE.
>>> IN THE MEANTIME, MUCH OF THE
ATTENTION IN THE NEWS MEDIA HAS
FOCUSED IN ON THE MENTAL HEALTH
OF ADAM LANZA, THE 20-YEAR-OLD
WHO COMMITTED THIS MASS MURDER
HERE AT THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IN NEWTOWN.
OUR CHIEF MEDICAL CORRESPONDENT
DR. SANJAY GUPTA IS JOINING US.
SANJAY, I WANT YOU TO PUT IN
PERSPECTIVE.
THERE HAVE BEEN THESE REPORTS
THAT ADAM LANZA HAD AUTISM.
SOME PEOPLE ARE JUMPING TO
CONCLUSIONS INAPPROPRIATELY.
GIVE US SOME PERSPECTIVE ON WHAT
THIS MEANS.
>> THERE ARE TWO IMPORTANT
POINTS HERE.
FIRST OF ALL, WHEN YOU TALK
ABOUT AUTISM OR ANYTHING ON THE
AUTISM SPECTRUM.
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT A NEURAL
DISORDER.
I THINK THE TERMS DO MATTER
HERE.
SECOND OF ALL, JUST THIS WHOLE
IDEA THAT IT'S LINKED WITH
VIOLENCE IN SOME WAY AND
SPECIFICALLY PREPLANNED
VIOLENCE, I THINK WE CAN
DISPENSE WITH THAT.
>> THERE'S NO EVIDENCE THAT
AUTISM WOULD GENERATE A MASS
MURDER LIKE THIS?
>> ABSOLUTELY NOT.
WE TALKED ABOUT THIS YESTERDAY,
BUT EVEN SINCE THEN I TALKED TO
A FEW MORE EXPERTS.
I LOOKED AT THE DEFINITIVE STUDY
ON THIS, WOLF, THE STUDY
EVERYONE QUOTES WHEN LOOKING AT
THIS EXACT ISSUE.
132 PEOPLE WERE STUDIED IN THAT
PARTICULAR STUDY.
OF THOSE, 3 PEOPLE HAD SOME
EVIDENCE OF VIOLENCE, SMALL
NUMBER, BUT NONE OF THEM HAD
WHAT WAS THOUGHT OF AS
PREPLANNED VIOLENCE.
THOSE ARE, IN FACT, REACTIONARY
VIOLENCE AND OUTBURST, NOT
SOMETHING THAT REQUIRED ANY SORT
OF PLANNING.
>> ARE THERE ANY OTHER MENTAL
ILLNESSES THAT COULD CAUSE THIS
KIND OF VIOLENCE?
>> SURE.
OTHER SORTS OF THINGS THAT YOU
THINK ABOUT WITH REGARD TO SOME
SORT OF MANIC THING.
SOME SORT OF LOSS OF JUDGMENT
AND INHIBITION OF JUDGMENT.
WE TALK ABOUT DEPRESSION.
OBVIOUSLY, ANGER ISSUES HERE.
BUT IN ASSOCIATION WITH MENTAL
ILLNESS, NOT BECAUSE OF AUTISM,
ASPERGER OR ANYTHING ELSE ALONE.
>> SOMETIMES YOU HEAR ABOUT
THESE ATROCITIES AND SOMETIMES
PEOPLE SAY, YOU KNOW, HE JUST
SNAPPED.
SO, MEDICALLY SPEAKING, WHAT
DOES THAT MEAN?
>> WHEN SOMEONE -- AGAIN, THAT
DOES REFER TO SOME SORT OF
REACTION TO SOMETHING, USUALLY.
OR SOME SORT OF SOMEBODY WAS
PREDISPOSED TO SOMETHING AND
SOMETHING PUSHED SOMEBODY OVER
THE EDGE.
THE DIFFERENCE, AGAIN, WOLF,
INVESTIGATORS ALWAYS THINK ABOUT
THIS AND ALSO IN MY FIELD,
FORENSIC MEDICAL EXAMINERS LOOK
AT THIS AND SOMETIMES YOU DON'T
KNOW THE ANSWER EXACTLY.
ONE OF THE THINGS YOU WANT TO
KNOW, WAS THERE EVIDENCE OF
PLANNING?
SOME SORT OF EVIDENCE OF
BECAUSE IF THERE WAS, IT REALLY
CHANGES THE DISCUSSION
COMPLETELY.
CHANGES IT FROM A LAW
ENFORCEMENT STANDPOINT WHICH IS
WHERE PEOPLE FOCUS THEIR
ATTENTION BUT ALSO FROM A
MEDICAL STANDPOINT.
FORENSIC MEDICAL EXAMINATION.
>> CORRECT ME IF I'M WRONG, AT
LEAST ANECDOTALLY IN COVERING
THESE STORIES, IT'S USUALLY A
MALE WHO COMMITS THIS KIND OF
MASS MURDER, NOT A FEMALE.
IS THERE A GENDER -RELATED ISSUE
HERE?
>> YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
AGAIN, THE NUMBERS DO BEAR THAT
OUT.
IF YOU LOOK, AGAIN, NOT JUST AT,
OBVIOUSLY, THE STUDY THAT I
TALKED ABOUT BUT ALL SORTS OF
THESE SORT OF VIOLENT ATTACKS
AND MASS MURDER TYPE OF ATTACKS,
THEY'RE GENERALLY MALE.
WHAT TO MAKE OF THAT IS UNCLEAR.
WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT NEURAL
DISORDER, WE DON'T KNOW FOR SURE
WHAT WAS GOING ON IN HIS MIND OR
WHAT HIS BACKGROUND IS, THAT IS
SOMETHING YOU TYPICALLY HAVE
SINCE BIRTH.
IT IS SOMETHING THAT IS
INHERITED.
IT'S AN INHERITED COMPONENT TO
IT AND EVEN WHILE YOU'RE
DEVELOPING AS A HUMAN BEING.
AGAIN, I SAY THAT TO DISTINGUISH
IT FROM MANY OTHER FORMS OF
MENTAL ILLNESS.
ALSO WITH REGARD TO GENDER, YOU
KNOW, IF THERE IS A MALE
PREPONDERANCE OF THIS AND A
GENETIC LINK, YOU CAN PUT THE
TWO AND TWO TOGETHER.
WE DON'T KNOW FOR SURE, BUT,
AGAIN, I THINK THAT'S WHAT
PEOPLE --
>> THE VIDEO GAMES.
YOU KNOW, THESE KIND OF VIOLENT
VIDEO GAMES, BOYS DO IT A LOT
MORE THAN GIRLS.
IS THERE A CONNECTION
POTENTIALLY?
>> I THINK THERE'S NO DOUBT
THERE IS A CONNECTION.
WOLF, LET ME SAY, THEY HAVE
KNOWN ABOUT A CONNECTION, NOT
WITH VIDEO GAMES BUT VIOLENT
PROGRAMMING FOR 40 YEARS.
WROTE ABOUT THIS IN 1972 AND
WROTE ABOUT IT AND OVER THE LAST
40 YEARS, BACK THEN IT WAS
TELEVISION BUT DIFFERENT SORTS
OF AVENUES HAVE HAPPENED NOW.
PRETTY GOOD SCIENTIFIC EVIDENCE
TO SHOW SOME KIND OF CONNECTION
BETWEEN VIDEO GAMING AND
VIOLENCE.
MOST PEOPLE WHO PLAY VIDEO GAMES
AREN'T VIOLENT, BUT THERE IS A
CONNECTION.
>> SANJAY, THANKS VERY MUCH.
GOOD ADVICE.
>>> WE'RE AWAITING THE NEWS
CONFERENCE, CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE GETTING READY TO GO TO
THE MICROPHONES HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, TO UPDATE US ON THE
INVESTIGATION.

>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
YOU CAN SEE THE LIVE PICTURES
HERE.
MICROPHONES STANDING BY EVERYONE
HERE FOR THE PRESS CONFERENCE
WITH LIEUTENANT VANCE FROM THE
STATE POLICE AND ALSO THE
STATE'S MEDICAL EXAMINER.
WE'RE EXPECTING THEM TO UPDATE
US ON SOME OF THE DETAILS THAT
THEY HAVE BEEN TELLING US THAT
THEY WILL FOCUS ON IN THIS NEXT
PRESS CONFERENCE.
FOR EXAMPLE, WE'LL KNOW ABOUT
THE WEAPONRY, THE CALIBER OF THE
WEAPONS THAT WERE USED AND
EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED, THE
TIMELINE OF THE EVENTS ON THIS
TERRIBLE, TERRIBLE MASSACRE THAT
HAPPENED ON FRIDAY MORNING.
WE'RE ALSO EXPECTED TO HEAR SOME
MORE INFORMATION ABOUT THE
AUTOPSIES THAT SHOULD, BY NOW,
HAVE BEEN PERFORMED ON THE
SHOOTER AND HIS MOTHER.
THOSE WERE THE LAST TWO THEY
WERE WAITING TO COMPLETE.
ROUGHLY TWO DOZEN JOURNALISTS
WHO ARE GATHERED HERE.
WE'RE EXPECTING SOME MORE TO
COME, AS WELL.
THEY TOLD US THIS PRESS
CONFERENCE WOULD HAPPEN IN THE
NEXT FEW MINUTES.
WE'VE HEARD THEY'RE ON THEIR
WAY.
AS SOON AS IT HAPPENS, WE WILL,
OBVIOUSLY, BRING THAT TO YOU
LIVE.
>>> THIS MORNING, CONNECTICUT'S
GOVERNOR TOLD CNN THAT THE
GUNMAN GOT INTO THE SCHOOL
LITERALLY BY USING THE ASSAULT
WEAPON TO SHOOT THE ENTRANCE
INTO THE BUILDING.
HE BLEW OUT A WHOLE BIG ENOUGH
THAT HE COULD WALK THROUGH.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER SAID THE
SEMI-AUTOMATIC RIFLE FOUND AT
THE SCENE WAS THE PRIMARY WEAPON
IN THE MASSACRE THAT EVERY
SINGLE PERSON HAD BEEN SHOT BY
THAT RIFLE AND, IN FACT, THE
SEVEN THAT HE HAD DONE AUTOPSIES
ON HAD BEEN SHOT MULTIPLE TIMES,
IN SOME CASES THREE TIMES AND IN
SOME CASES 11 TIMES.
WE'RE EXPECTING PRESIDENT OBAMA
HERE IN NEWTOWN LATER THIS
AFTERNOON.
HE'S GOING TO THANK FAMILIES,
FIRST RESPONDERS AND THEN MEET
WITH THE VICTIMS' FAMILY
MEMBERS.
HE'S ALSO GOING TO SPEAK AT AN
INTERFAITH VIGIL THAT WILL BE
HELD LATER THIS EVENING.
SOME OF THE THINGS WE'RE
MONITORING HERE FOR YOU FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>>> ALSO FAKE A LOOK AT HOW SOME
OF THE DETAILS HERE IN NEWTOWN
PLAYED OUT ON FACEBOOK AND
TWITTER AS THE MEDIA HAD
CONFLICTING STORIES.
A CRITICAL LOOK AT HOW THAT WAS
HANDLED, STRAIGHT AHEAD.
Wooohooo....Hahaahahaha!
Oh...there you go.
I'm gonna stand
up to her!
No you're not.
I know.
You know Ronny folks who save
hundreds of dollars
switching to GEICO
sure are happy.
How happy are they Jimmy?
Happier than a witch in
a broom factory.
Get happy. Get GEICO.
Fifteen minutes could save you
fifteen percent or more.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
THIS IS ANOTHER!
TA-DAA!
TRY CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG.
IT CLEANS SO WELL AND YOU CAN
USE UP TO FOUR TIMES LESS
THAN THE LEADING VALUE
BRAND.
OH! THERE IT IS.
THANKS SON.
HEY!
[ Female Announcer ]
CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG
HAS A DURACLEAN TEXTURE
THAT CAN HELP YOU GET CLEAN
WHILE STILL USING LESS.
AND IT'S FOUR TIMES STRONGER
VERSUS THE LEADING VALUE BRAND.
CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG HELPS KEEP
YOU AND YOUR UNDERWEAR CLEAN.
WE ALL GO. WHY NOT ENJOY THE GO
WITH CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG?
>>> CONTINUING OUR DISCUSSION OF
THE TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT, SEE
THERE THE MEMORIAL, THE CHILDREN
AND THE GROWNUPS WHO DIED.
WE'RE JOINED NOW FROM NEW YORK
BY JEFF JARVIS RUNS THE
JOURNALISM PROGRAM AND HAVE TO
GO TO SOLEDAD O'BRIEN WITH
BREAKING NEWS OUT OF
CONNECTICUT.
>> THANKS, I APPRECIATE THAT.
LET'S LISTEN IN AS THEY'RE
GETTING READY TO START THIS
PRESS CONFERENCE.
I'M ABOUT TEN YARDS AWAY AND
LOOKS LIKE LIEUTENANT VANCE IS
ABOUT TO SPEAK.
HERE HE GOES.
>> CRIME DETECTIVES ARE STILL AT
THE SCENES OF THE SCHOOL AND AT
THE SECONDARY SCENE.
WE'RE STILL ACTIVELY WORKING
THOSE AREAS.
THERE'S NOTHING NEW TO REPORT
RELATIVE TO THE INVESTIGATION.
SUFFICE TO SAY THAT IT IS MOVING
FORWARD.
AS I SAID YESTERDAY AND I WILL
NOT AND CANNOT DETAIL PIECES OF
THE INVESTIGATION, BUT I CAN
TELL YOU THAT WE HAVE RECOVERED
EVIDENCE, CONTRARY TO SOME OF
THE NEWS REPORTS THAT HAVE BEEN
OUT THERE.
WE HAVE RECOVERED SOME EVIDENCE.
IT IS BEING ANALYZED AND IT IS
BEING PROCESSED.
THE WEAPONRY INVOLVED, WE ARE
TRACING THEM HISTORICALLY ALL
THE WAY BACK TO WHEN THEY WERE
ON THE WORK BENCH BEING
ASSEMBLED AND BEING EXAMINED AND
LOOKED AT WITH OUR FEDERAL
PARTNERS.
IN ADDITION, THE POST-MORTEM
EXAMINATION BY THE CHIEF MEDICAL
EXAMINER IS ONGOING.
HOPEFULLY EARLIER THIS AFTERNOON
WE'LL BE ABLE TO RELEASE FACTUAL
INFORMATION ON THE LAST TWO
DECEASED IN THIS CASE.
AS YOU KNOW, THERE IS
PRESIDENTIAL BUSINESS SCHEDULED
THIS AFTERNOON.
I DON'T HAVE DETAILS ON THAT.
I KNOW THAT'S BEING PUT OUT VIA
WASHINGTON, SO, WE'LL LEAVE THAT
AS IS.
WE ARE IN THE PROCESS, I'M SURE
YOU'VE SEEN, AS I EXPLAINED TO
YOU, WE HAVE MULTIPLE CRIME
SCENES BUT STICKING SPECIFICALLY
WITH THE SCHOOL, THE SCHOOL
CRIME SCENE, THE BUILDING ITSELF
IS STILL BEING WORKED ON.
REMEMBER I TOLD YOU WE HAD A
SECONDARY CRIME SCENE AND THAT
WAS ALL THE VEHICLES ON THE
EXTERIOR OF THE SCHOOL.
OUR DETECTIVES HAVE EXAMINED
EACH AND EVERY ONE OF THEM,
SEARCHED EACH AND EVERY ONE OF
THEM AND WE'RE BEGINNING TO
RELEASE THOSE BACK TO THEIR
OWNERS.
SO, SLOWLY BUT SURELY WE'RE
BEGINNING TO COMPLETE THE
EXTERIOR PART OF THE CRIME
SCENE.
THE GOVERNOR AND LIEUTENANT
GOVERNOR ARE ON SITE AND HAVE
BEEN ACTIVELY INVOLVED TODAY.
ONE THING THAT'S BECOMING
SOMEWHAT OF A CONCERN AND THAT
IS MISINFORMATION IS BEING
POSTED ON SOCIAL MEDIA SITES.
THERE HAS BEEN MISINFORMATION
COMING FROM PEOPLE POSING AS THE
SHOOTER IN THIS CASE, POSING
USING OTHER I.D.s, MIMICKING
THIS CRIME AND CRIME SCENE AND
CRIMINAL ACTIVITY THAT TOOK
PLACE IN THIS COMMUNITY.
THERE'S BEEN SOME THINGS AND
SOMEWHAT OF A THREATENING
MANNER.
IT IS IMPORTANT TO NOTE THAT WE
HAVE DISCUSSED WITH FEDERAL
AUTHORITIES THAT THESE, THESE
ISSUES ARE CRIMES, THEY WILL BE
INVESTIGATED STATEWIDE AND
FEDERALLY, AND PROSECUTION WILL
TAKE PLACE WHEN PEOPLE
PERPETRATING THIS INFORMATION
ARE IDENTIFIED.
AGAIN, ALL INFORMATION RELATIVE
TO THIS CASE IS COMING FROM
THESE MICROPHONES AND ANY
INFORMATION COMING FROM OTHER
SOURCES CANNOT BE CONFIRMED AND,
IN MANY CASES, IT HAS BEEN FOUND
AS INACCURATE.
SO, I SIMPLY, THAT'S THE NEWEST
TWIST TODAY THAT WE WANT TO MAKE
SURE THAT'S PERFECTLY CLEAR THAT
SOCIAL MEDIA WEBSITES THAT
CONTAIN INFORMATION RELATIVE TO
THIS CASE ARE NOT BEING POSTED
BY THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE,
ARE NOT BEING POSTED BY THE
NEWTOWN POLICE, ARE NOT BEING
POSTED BY ANY AUTHORITIES IN
THIS CASE.
SO, ANY OF THAT INFORMATION AND
PEOPLE THAT ARE THAT ARE PUTTIN
INFORMATION UP THERE IN ANY
MANNER ALL RIGHT, CAN BE
CONSTRUED AS A VIOLATION OF
STATE OR FEDERAL LAW WILL BE
PROSECUTED.
WILL BE INVESTIGATED AND
QUESTIONS, I CAN TAKE A FEW,
UNDERSTANDING WE STILL ARE
ACTIVE IN THIS CASE.
OKAY.
>> HAS A VERY SPECIFIC TIMELINE
OF HOW THIS EVENT HAPPENED.
I'M WONDERING IF YOU CAN, IN
FACT, CONFIRM THAT TIMELINE THAT
IS BEING REPORTED IN GREAT
DETAIL BY THE "HARTFORD
COURANT."
>> VERY GOOD QUESTION.
I'M THE ONLY ONE SPEAKING ABOUT
THIS CASE TO EVERY MEMBER OF THE
MEDIAP.
I CANNOT STATE HEAVILY ENOUGH I
HAVE NOT AND WILL NOT PUT OUT A
TIMELINE IN THIS CRIMINAL
INVESTIGATION AS IT IS UNDER
WAY.
IT IS INAPPROPRIATE.
WE WILL NOT DO THAT.
ANY SOURCES THAT ARE PUTTING OUT
ANY KIND OF INFORMATION LIKE
THAT DOES NOT COME FROM THE
OFFICIAL INVESTIGATING AGENCY,
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
ASSISTED BY THE NEWTOWN POLICE
DEPARTMENT.
WE WILL NOT PUT THAT OUT AS THE
INVESTIGATION IS ONGOING.
>> I HAVE NOT READ IT.
I CAN TELL YOU THAT.
WE HAVE NOT PUT OUT ANY TIMELINE
INFORMATION.
>> YOU HAVE SAID THERE WERE TWO
PLACES INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
CAN YOU CONFIRM THAT THE
PRINCIPAL AND THE PSYCHOLOGIST
WAS SHOT NEAR THE FRONT DOOR AND
THE CHILDREN AND THE TEACHERS
AND OTHER WORKERS WERE IN
CLASSROOMS?
>> AGAIN, WHAT I STATED RELATIVE
TO THE INTERIOR CRIME SCENE, WAS
THAT THE SHOOTING TOOK PLACE IN
A SINGULAR SECTION OF THE
SCHOOL, THAT INVOLVED TWO
CLASSROOMS AND A HALLWAY.
THAT'S AS MUCH AS WE SAID ABOUT
THAT.
WE CANNOT AND WILL NOT DESCRIBE
THE LOCATION OF THE DECEASED IN
THIS INVESTIGATION.
WE WON'T DO THAT.
>> YES, SIR.
>> SIR?
>> SAID YOUR INVESTIGATION OF
FIREARMS.
>> YES, SIR.
>> THE SHOOTER WAS TAKEN BY HIS
FAMILY MEMBER TO A SHOOTING
RANGE [ INAUDIBLE ].
GONE SHOOTING WITH HIS MOTHER?
>> I DON'T KNOW THAT, QUITE
FRANKLY.
AND THAT'S WHAT I'M TRYING TO
GET PEOPLE TO UNDERSTAND IS THAT
WE CAN'T TAKE SEGMENTS OF AN
INVESTIGATION AND DISCUSS THAT
PUBLICLY BECAUSE SOMETHING TAKEN
OUT OF CONTEXT COULD BE
MISINTERPRETED, IT COULD BE
MISINTERPRETED AND NOT FACTUAL
ONCE IT'S MISINTERPRETED.
THEREFORE, I DON'T, NUMBER ONE,
I DON'T KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT THAT
PARTICULAR STATEMENT YOU JUST
MADE AND NUMBER TWO, EVEN IF I
DID, I WOULD SAY LET US PUT IT
INTO THE CONTENTS OF THE
INVESTIGATION SO THAT WE CAN
MANAGE IT AND YOU CAN GET A
WHOLE COMPLETE PICTURE OF EXA
EXACTLY WHAT'S GOING ON.
>> DO I KNOW ANYTHING MORE?
THE FOUR FIREARMS WORKING WITH
OUR FEDERAL PARTNERS AND AS I
SAID IN MY STATEMENT WE ARE
ANALYZING, EXAMINING, WE'LL
TRACE THEM BACK TO THEIR ORIGIN,
WE'LL TRACE EVERY STEP OF THE
WAY, AND EVERY TIME THAT WE CAN,
WHERE THEY WERE USED, HOW THEY
WERE USED WILL BE EXAMINED FOR
RENICALLY.
A GREAT DEAL OF WORK MUST BE
DONE ON THOSE WEAPONS.
>> [ INAUDIBLE ].
>> ANY EVIDENCE THAT ANY OF THE
OTHER WEAPONS --
>> I CAN'T ANSWER THAT QUESTION.
I DO NOT KNOW.
OUR DETECTIVES WILL BE ABLE TO
ANSWER THAT QUESTION AT THE
CONCLUSION OF THE INVESTIGATION.
>> YES, SIR.
>> I KNOW YOU CAN'T GO INTO
DETAIL ABOUT WHAT YOU'RE FINDING
BUT HOW CONFIDENT DO YOU FEEL
YOU WILL EVENTUALLY GET A GOOD
PICTURE?
>> I AM CONFIDENT THAT WE
WILL PUT EVERY SINGLE RESOURCE
THAT WE HAVE INTO THIS
INVESTIGATION AND THAT WE WILL
ANSWER EVERY SINGLE QUESTION
THAT IS HUMANLY POSSIBLE AT THE
CONCLUSION OF THIS CASE.
WE'LL EXAMINE EVERY PIECE OF
EVIDENCE, WE'LL SPEAK TO EVERY
SINGLE WITNESS THAT CAN HAVE ANY
IMPACT ON THIS CASE AND OUR
GOAL, OUR GOAL IS TO ANSWER
EVERY SINGLE QUESTION.
>> DO YOU THINK NO NOTE, NO
ALIVE SHOOTER, HOW CONFIDENT DO
YOU FEEL THAT YOU'LL EVENTUALLY
BE ABLE IT TO PUT TOGETHER
SOMETHING PEOPLE WOULD
CONSIDER --
>> JUST TO SAY, WE HAVE NOT
STATED WHAT EVIDENCE WE HAVE AND
HAVE NOT COLLECTED.
I WANT TO MAKE THAT PERFECTLY
CLEAR.
HOW CONFIDENT AM I?
WE HAVE THE BEST OF THE BEST
WORKING ON THIS CASE.
WE HAVE OUR MAJOR CRIME
DETECTIVES, WE HAVE FEDERAL
AUTHORITIES, NEWTOWN
INVESTIGATORS, WE HAVE
EVERYTHING AND EVERYBODY
FOCUSING ON THIS CASE AS
EVERYONE KNOWS IT'S A HUGE CASE,
IT'S A HUGE CASE.
WE'RE USING EVERY SINGLE
RESOURCE AND OUR GOAL IS TO
PAINT A COMPLETE PICTURE SO THAT
WE ALL KNOW AND THE PUBLIC KNOWS
EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
COUPLE MORE FOLKS.
>> [ INAUDIBLE ].
>> MAGAZINES ON THE GUN?
>> I CANNOT.
I CANNOT.
>> SOCIAL MEDIA WHAT DO YOU MAKE
OF THAT?
>> WELL, BEST I CAN EXPLAIN, I'M
NOT A SOCIAL MEDIA EXPERT, I'M
NOT GOING TO CLAIM TO BE, BUT
THERE HAVE BEEN INDICATIONS THAT
THERE HAVE BEEN QUOTES BY PEOPLE
WHO ARE POSING AS THE SHOOTER.
YOU CAN GO ON DIFFERENT FACEBOOK
PAGES AND FIND THIS INFORMATION
OUT.
I KNOW MEMBERS OF THE PRESS
HAVE.
AND SUFFICE IT TO SAY THAT THE
INFORMATION CAN, IN FACT, BE --
HAS, IN FACT, BEEN DEEMED AS
THREATENING, IT'S BEEN
INACCURATE, PEOPLE POSING AS
OTHER PEOPLE, AND DISCUSSING
WITH FEDERAL AUTHORITIES THEY
BELIEVE IT'S A VIOLATION OF
STATE OR FEDERAL LAW AND
WARRANTS AN INVESTIGATION.
ANYONE PERPETRATING THAT
INFORMATION, COULD, IN FACT, BE
SUBJECT TO ARREST AND BE
PROSECUTED FEDERALLY.
>> HAS ANYONE BEEN IDENTIFIED,
QUESTIONED?
>> THEY'RE WORKING ON THAT RIGHT
NOW.
THIS IS BRAND NEW INFORMATION,
WE GOT IT AS WE WERE COMING TO
THIS PRESS CONFERENCE.
COUPLE MORE QUICK QUESTIONS.
YES, MA'AM.
>> [ INAUDIBLE ] ANY MORE
INFORMATION ON THE OTHER TWO
BODIES?
>> THE MINUTE I HAVE THAT WE'LL
REDUCE IT TO WRITING AND BRING
IT UP TO YOU, BRING MORE COPIES
OF THE NAMES FROM YESTERDAY IF
ANYONE NEEDS IT.
CERTAINLY THE MINUTE WE HAVE
THAT WE'LL BRING THAT UP TO YOU.
>> YES, MA'AM.
>> DO YOU KNOW WHEN THE BODIES
WILL BE RELEASED TO THE
FAMILIES?
>> THEY HAVE ALREADY STARTED
THAT PROCESS.
>> YES, MA'AM.
>> IS THERE ANY IDEA OF WHEN THE
STUDENTS CAN RETURN TO CLASS AND
WHAT CAN YOU SAY TO PARENTS
ABOUT SAFETY IN SCHOOLS?
>> WHAT'S IMPORTANT TO NOTE
ABOUT SAFETY IN SCHOOL IS FROM
THE EDUCATIONAL COMMISSIONER IN
THE STATE OF CONNECTICUT WORKING
WITH THE GOVERNOR'S OFFICE IT'S
BEING EXAMINED ON A LOCAL AND
STATEWIDE BASIS.
THERE ARE MANY PLANS IN PLACE
FOR EMERGENCY PURPOSES IN ALL
THE SCHOOLS IN CONNECTICUT.
ALL OF THEM ARE BEING REEXAMINED
AND CERTAINLY PARENTS SHOULD, IN
FACT, BE CONFIDENT THAT LAW
ENFORCEMENT IN EVERY COMMUNITY,
STATE POLICE, LOCAL POLICE, THE
EDUCATORS, THE LEADERS OF THE
SCHOOL SYSTEMS ARE DOING
EVERYTHING THEY CAN TO MAKE SURE
THAT THE SCHOOLS IN CONNECTICUT
ARE SAFE.
I WOULD LIKE THE LIEUTENANT TO
TALK ABOUT THE SCHOOLS IN
NEWTOWN.
ONE SECOND.
>> YES.
WE'VE BEEN WORKING CLOSELY WITH
THE SUPERINTENDENT OF SCHOOLS
HERE.
OBVIOUSLY WE'RE STILL VERY
SENSITIVE TO THE FAMILY IN THIS
SITUATION.
WE WANT TO MOVE FORWARD VERY
SLOWLY AND RESPECTFULLY.
THEY HAVE SOME TENTATIVE PLANS
AS FAR AS MOVING FORWARD WITH
THE SCHOOL AND THE SCHOOL SYSTEM
WILL BE PUTTING THOSE OUT IN THE
NEAR FUTURE.
>> DO YOU IMAGINE THAT CHILDREN
WILL EVER RETURN TO CLASS IN
THAT BUILDING?
>> YOU KNOW, AT THIS TIME IT'S
TOO EARLY TO SAY.
BUT I WOULD FIND IT VERY
DIFFICULT FOR THEM TO DO THAT.
BUT CERTAINLY THAT'S ONE OF THE
THINGS THAT THEY'RE GOING TO
HAVE TO LOOK INTO, YES.
>> THEY ARE GOING TO TRANSPORT
KIDS TO MONROE STARTING LATER
THIS WEEK, RIGHT?
>> THAT'S ONE OF THE PLANS THAT
WE'RE LOOKING INTO.
IT'S TENTATIVE PLANS RIGHT NOW.
BUT AS WE SAID, WE'RE TRYING TO
BE AS RESPECTFUL AS WE CAN.
WE WANT TO KEEP THESE KIDS
TOGETHER.
WE NEED SUPPORT OF EACH OTHER.
>> COUPLE MORE QUICK QUESTIONS.
YES, SIR.
>> WITHOUT REVEALING A TIMELINE
CAN YOU SAY MORE ABOUT
[ INAUDIBLE ] BREAKS A WINDOW,
TURNS LEFT, RIGHT?
GIVE US A GENERAL SENSE OF HIS
MOVEMENTS AND HOW --
>> THE MOST GENERAL I COULD BE
IS IT HAS TO BE VERY GENERAL WAS
THAT THE SCHOOL WAS -- FORCIBLY
ENTERED THE SCHOOL FACILITY
ITSELF.
OKAY.
ENCOUNTERED JUST ENCOUNTERED
STAFF, STUDENTS AND THE TRAGEDY
OCCURRED.
THAT'S AS MUCH AS I WANT TO GO.
>> CAN YOU TELL US --
>> IS SURVIVORS, BEEN ABLE TO
TALK TO THEM?
>> OUR PEOPLE ARE TALKING WITH
EVERYBODY.
SLOWLY BUT SURELY.
BUT METHODICALLY TOO.
THIS IS NOT SOMETHING THAT --
THIS IS SOMETHING WHERE PEOPLE'S
HEARTS ARE BROKEN AND AS WE ALL
WELL KNOW AND WE HAVE TO BE
SENSITIVE AND WE ARE MOVING AS
QUICKLY AND EFFICIENTLY AS WE
CAN.
THE PEOPLE WE CAN TALK TO, YES,
WE HAVE.
WE HAVE SPOKEN TO MANY, MANY
WITNESSES.
THERE ARE MANY MORE WITNESSES TO
SPEAK TO, INCLUDING AND NOT
LIMITED TO MAYBE EVEN SPEAKING
WITH YOUNGSTERS.
>> WHAT ABOUT THE WOUNDED?
>> WE HAVE SPOKEN, YES, WITH THE
WOUNDED.
>> LIEUTENANT, CAN YOU TELL US
WHAT --
>> WE WON'T DISCUSS WHAT
WITNESSES HAVE PUT FORTH.
TAKING OUT OF CONTEXT, WE'LL
INCLUDE THAT IN THE REPORT AND
FINAL SUMMARY OF WHAT TOOK
PLACE.
>> ALL RIGHT.
ONE MORE YES, SIR.
>> [ INAUDIBLE ] EVERYONE KEEPS
ASKING THAT QUESTION AND I HAVE
TO SAY TO YOU, THAT FOR US TO BE
ABLE TO GIVE YOU A SUMMARY OF
THE MOTIVE WE HAVE TO COMPLETE
THE INVESTIGATION AND HAVE THE
WHOLE PICTURE BEFORE WE CAN SAY
HOPEFULLY HOW AND WHY THIS
OCCURRED.
THAT'S NOT GOING TO COME
QUICKLY.
>> LEFT ANY WRITINGS OR NOTES
BEHIND?
>> AGAIN, I CANNOT DETAIL
EVIDENCE.
WE DON'T DO THAT.
IT'S SIMPLY STATED WE HAVE A
GREAT DEAL OF EVIDENCE THAT
WE'RE ANALYZING AND THAT'S A