SURE EVERYBODY ELSE IS SAFE.
>> SOME PEOPLE WERE EVEN LIKE
FELT LIKE THEY HAD A STOMACH
ACHE.
>> IT'S THE MOST TRAUMATIC EVENT
I EVER EXPERIENCED OR EVEN
CONSIDERED.
>> THEY LET THE STUDENTS OUT AND
MY DAUGHTER AND HER TEACHER OUT
AND AS MY DAUGHTER IS WALKING
OUT, SHE DID SEE IT.
>> THIS IS THE WORST SCHOOL YARD
CATASTROPHE IN HISTORY.
>> QUITE A FEW KIDS PERISHED.
>> BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
>> THE PARENTS WERE WAITING FOR
THEIR CHILDREN TO COME OUT AND
THOUGHT THEY WERE STILL ALIVE.
>> HOW DO YOU WRAP YOUR MIND
AROUND SOMETHING LIKE THIS?
>> THE COMMUNITY TRYING TO MAKE
SENSE OF WHAT THEIR GOVERNOR
SAID WAS EVIL VISITED UPON THIS
COMMUNITY TODAY.
I'M ASHLEIGH BANFIELD IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
ANDERSON COOPER 360 STARTS NOW.
>> THANKS VERY MUCH AND GOOD
EVENING.
THERE IS ONLY ONE STORY TONIGHT.
YOU KNOW WHAT IT IS.
WE HAVE NEW DETAILS TO TELL BUT
AND WE WON'T PRETEND WE
UNDERSTAND IT ANY BETTER THAN
AFTER IT HAPPENED.
IT IS A HORROR BEYOND WORDS.
KIDS AS YOUNG AS 5 YEARS OLD.
SADLY TO THE NAMES COLUMBINE AND
JONESBORO, WE HAVE TO ADD
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT TO VIRGINIA
TECH ADD SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY,
THE SECOND DEADLIEST SCHOOL
SHOOTING EVER.
20 LITTLE KIDS AND SEVEN ADULTS
AND THE SHOOTER WHO TOOK HIS OWN
LIFE.
ALL IN A CLOSE-KNIT QUIET
COMMUNITY 90 MINUTES FROM NEW
YORK.
WE WILL GIVE YOU THE LATEST
INFORMATION, BUT WHAT WE WILL
NOT DO IS REPEAT THE SHOOTER'S
NAME OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
WE DON'T WANT HISTORY TO
REMEMBER THIS MURDERER.
WE WANT HISTORY TO REMEMBER THE
VICTIMS, THE TEACHERS AND THE
CHILDREN, THOSE WHOSE LIVES HAVE
BEEN UNFAIRLY TAKEN.
WE HAVE A TEAMWORKING ON THE
TRAGEDY AND WE HAVE SOLEDAD
O'BRIEN ON THE SCENE.
THERE VIGILS TONIGHT.
WE WILL BE CHECKING IN WITH HER
SHORTLY.
VIGILS TO TELL YOU ABOUT AS THE
PEOPLE COME TO GRIPS WITH WHAT
HAPPENED.
SO MUCH HAPPENED AND SO MUCH WE
HAVE LEARNED SINCE THIS MORNING.
RIGHT NOW THERE IS AN ACTIVE
CRIME SCENE AND MANY OF THE
BODIES STILL WHERE THEY FELL.
STILL INSIDE THAT SCHOOL
INCLUDING THAT OF THE KILLER.
WE DO AT LEAST TELL YOU HIS NAME
ONCE.
IT'S ADAM LANZA.
WE WON'T BE SAYING IT MUCH
TONIGHT.
HE WAS 20 AND HIS MOTHER TAUGHT
AT THE SCHOOL.
SHE WAS FOUND DEAD AT THE FAMILY
HOME, UNCLEAR WHEN OR HOW SHE
DIED.
SHE BOUGHT THE WEAPONS HER SON
USED LEGALLY.
THE POLICE IN HOBOKEN TOOK THE
KILLER'S OLDER BROTHER IN FOR
QUESTIONING.
THEY DO NOT LABEL HIM A SUSPECT
AND NO WORD OF WHY HE IS IN
CUSTODY.
LET'S START AT THE BEGINNING.
>> THE CONNECTICUT SCHOOL
DISTRICT ON LOCKDOWN.
>> THE FIRST WORD WAS CHILLING
AND IT GOT WORSE.
>> MULTIPLE FATALITIES INVOLVED
IN THE SHOOTING AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> WITH EACH NEW REPORT THE
HORROR DEEPENED.
>> THE REPORTS SAY THE NUMBER OF
DEAD CLOSER TO 30 THAN TO 20 AND
SADLY MOST OF THEM ARE CHILDREN.
>> EVERY DETAIL AND EVERY FACT
BROUGHT MORE SADNESS.
EACH FRESH PIECE OF INFORMATION
A PART OF THE PICTURE.
A SCHOOL, KINDERGARTEN THROUGH
FOURTH GRADE, A SANCTUARY THAT
WAS SUPPOSED TO BE A PLACE OF
SAFETY TORN APART.
>> SHE HEARD THE INTERCOM COME
ON THE SCHOOL AND HEARD A SCREAM
AND HEARD A GUNSHOT.
TWO GUNSHOTS.
THEN THE SCHOOL WENT INTO
LOCKDOWN.
>> A STUDENT'S TEENAGE BIG
BROTHER DESCRIBING THE SOUNDS OF
GUNMEN ON THE LOOSE AT SANDY
HOOK.
>> ON AND OFF DUTY TROOPERS
RESPONDED AND WITH NEWTOWN
POLICE IMMEDIATELY UPON ARRIVAL
ENTERED THE SCHOOL AND BEGAN A
COMPLETE SHOOTER'S SEARCH OF THE
BUILDING.
>> THEY ARRIVED TO CARNAGE AND
THE KILLER SAID A SOURCE WAS
DRESSED FOR BATTLE IN BLACK
FATIGUES AND ARMED FOR MASS
MURDER WITH TWO PISTOLS AND A
MILITARY-STYLE RIFLE.
IN PARTS OF THE SCHOOL, STUDENTS
WERE TOLD TO HIDE IN CORNERS.
TEACHERS RISKED THEIR LIVES TO
PULL BOYS AND GIRLS TO SAFETY.
>> SO GRATEFUL TO THE TEACHER
WHO SAVED HIM.
>> THE TEACHER SAVED HIS LIFE?
>> SHE DEFINITELY DID.
HE HAD BULLETS GOING BY HIM AND
SHE GRABBED HIM AND ANOTHER
CHILD AND PULLED THEM INTO A
CLASSROOM.
>> THEY WERE EVACUATED INTO A
FIREHOUSE WHERE FRANTIC PARENTS
DESCENDED.
>> I'M STILL TERRIFY AND IN
SHOCK.
I DON'T KNOW EVERYTHING THAT
HAPPENED.
I KNOW THERE PEOPLE MISSING THAT
HAVE BEEN TAKEN TO THE HOSPITAL.
>> HIS SON WAS OKAY AND HIS
KEEPER WAS ALIVE AS WELL.
20 OTHER CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS
WERE KILLED.
THE DEAD BELIEVED TO INCLUDE
SANDY HOOK'S SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST
AND THE PRINCIPAL.
POLICE DISCOVERED ANOTHER ADULT
VICTIM, THE GUNMAN'S MOTHER
REPORTEDLY AT HOME IN NEWTOWN.
THE GUNMAN TOO IS DEAD.
POLICE FIRED NO SHOTS.
A TIGHT KNIT COMMUNITY INCLUDING
A NURSE WHO RUSHED TO HELP.
SHOCK AND DISTRAUGHT.
>> IS IT BECAUSE OF WHAT YOU
SAW?
>> ONE OF THE COPS SAID IT'S THE
WORST THING HE HAD EVER SEEN IN
HIS ENTIRE CAREER, BUT WHEN THEY
TOLD THE PARENTS, ALL THE
PARENTS WERE WAITING FOR THEIR
CHILDREN TO COME OUT.
THEY THOUGHT THEY WERE STILL
ALIVE.
THERE WAS 20 PARENTS WHO WERE
TOLD THEIR CHILDREN ARE DEAD.
IT WAS AWFUL.
>> AWFUL AND LATE TODAY SPEAKING
FOR THE NATION, BUT ALSO AS A
FATHER, AN EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT
OBAMA FOUGHT BACK TEARS.
>> THIS EVENING MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT
IN EAMERICA WILL DO.
HUG OUR CHILDREN TIGHTER AND
TELL THEM WE LOVE THEM AND WE
WILL REMIND EACH OTHER HOW
DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
FAMILIES IN CONNECTICUT CANNOT
DO THAT TONIGHT.
THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT NOW.
>> WE WILL BRING YOU ALL OF
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S COMMENTS LATER
ON IN THIS HOUR AHEAD.
SOLEDAD O'BRIEN IS ON THE SCENE
WITH JAY PAUL VANCE WITH THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE.
SOLEDAD?
>> Reporter: JOINING HIM IS
GEORGE SINKO.
YOU SPEND A LONG TIME FOR THE
FULL DAY ON THE SCENE.
YOU CAME BACK FROM BEING INSIDE
THE SCENE.
YOU WILL PROCESS THE SCENE
THROUGH SUNDAY.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN EXACTLY?
>> A LOT OF WORK GOES INTO A
CRIMINAL INVESTIGATION LIKE
THIS.
THE PRIORITY LIKE THAT IS
IDENTIFYING THE VICTIMS.
WE SAID 18 CHILDREN IN THERE AND
SIX ADULTS.
THE SHOOTER.
WE NEED TO POSITIVE LIE IDENTIFY
WHICH IS WHICH.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER'S OFFICE IS
WITH THEM NOW IN THAT PROCESS.
WE ARE HOPEFUL WE CAN ACCOMPLISH
THAT BY SOMETIME IN THE EARLY
MORNING HOURS.
>> DO YOU MEAN TO TELL ME THE
BODIES OF THE CHILDREN AND THOSE
KILLED ARE STILL WHERE THEY
FELL?
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
YES.
>> THEY WILL BE THERE.
HAVE YOU ALLOWED THE PARENTS TO
SEE THEIR CHILDREN.
>> NO.
THIS IS A CRIME SCENE.
WE NEED TO IDENTIFY THEM.
WE HAVE A TENTATIVE
IDENTIFICATION, BUT WE NEED TO
POSITIVELY IDENTIFY THEM AND WE
ARE DOING IT AS QUICKLY AS WE
POSSIBLY CAN.
>> YOU TALKED IN OTHER PRESS
CONFERENCES ABOUT THE PARTNERS
YOU HAVE IN THIS INVESTIGATION.
CAN YOU FILL ME IN ON WHAT THEY
ARE TELLING ME ABOUT WHAT'S
HAPPENING IN HOBOKEN WHERE WE
KNOW THE SHOOTER'S BROTHER HAS
BEEN INTERVIEWED BY OFFICIALS
THERE.
WE KNOW THAT THE SHOOTER'S
FATHER HAS BEEN TALKING TO LAW
ENFORCEMENT AS WELL.
>> WE HAVE NOT IDENTIFIED
ANYONE.
WE WILL NOT IDENTIFY ANYONE YET
BUT WE ARE WORKING WITH PARTNERS
AS NEEDED.
AS THEY CROSS THE LINE AND
DETERMINE THEY NEED INFORMATION
OUT OF STATE REGARDLESS OF WHAT
IT MIGHT BE.
WE WILL GET THEM TO ACCOMPLISH
THAT TASK FOR US.
THERE HAD BEEN ISSUES IN NEW
JERSEY AND OTHER STATES WHERE
OUR INVESTIGATORS HAVE CONTACTED
THE AGENCIES TO ASSIST US IN
THIS CASE.
>> LET ME ASK YOU A QUESTION IF
I CAN.
WE HAVE BEEN TOLD THAT THE
PERSON WHO IS BELIEVED TO BE THE
SHOOTER, NOW DECEASED, IN THE
BUILDING STILL, HAD NO CRIMINAL
RECORD AS FAR AS WE KNOW.
THERE OFTEN THINGS WE CALL KNOWN
TO POLICE.
A FAMILY HAD BEEN CONTACTING
POLICE AND YOU AS A POLICE
OFFICER WOULD KNOW THEM.
CAN YOU TELL ME MORE ABOUT THE
FAMILY.
>> AT THIS TIME WE ARE NOT GOING
TO COMMENT ON THE FAMILY AS THE
LIEUTENANT SAID.
WE ARE NOT CONFIRMING IDENTITIES
UNTIL WE ARE SURE POSITIVELY WHO
WE HAVE HERE.
WE ARE GOING TO TRY TO DO THAT
TOMORROW.
>> IS THERE ANY NARRATIVE THAT
YOU HAVE BEEN ABLE TO PIECE
TOGETHER ABOUT WHAT EXACTLY
HAPPENED?
WE HAVE INFORMATION ABOUT THE
WEAPONRY AND ABOUT THE VICTIMS.
WE HAVE INFORMATION ABOUT PEOPLE
IN DIFFERENT STATES NOW BEING
QUESTIONED.
IS THERE ANY STORY THAT ANSWERS
THE BIG QUESTION WHICH IS WHY?
>> I DON'T THINK SO.
THAT'S SOMETHING THAT WE WILL DO
TO WORK TOGETHER.
WE WILL LEAVE NO STONE UNTURNED.
WE'LL GO BACK AND UNCOVER EVERY
BIT OF INFORMATION AND TRY TO
ANSWER THE QUESTION AS TO WHY.
WE CONSIDER AN INVESTIGATION
LIKE THIS FOOB R TO BE MASSIVE.
IT'S LIKE EYE PUZZLE.
WE HAVE TO PUT THE PIECESING TO
TO DRAW A PICTURE AS TO HOW AND
WHY THIS OCCURRED.
>> THERE HAVE BEEN REPORT THAT
IS THE SHOOTER AND YOU ARE NOT
NAMING HIM, BUT HE HAS BEEN
NAMED IN REPORTS HAD A
PERSONALITY DISORDER.
OR IN SOME DESCRIPTIONS A MENTAL
DISORDER.
YOU CAN CONFIRM THAT?
>> WE CAN'T.
WE CAN'T DISCUSS AT THIS POINT
IN TIME ANYTHING TO DO WITH ANY
OF THE VICTIMS OR THE DECEASED
WHATSOEVER UNTIL WE ARE PREPARED
TO DO SO.
WE ANTICIPATE THAT WILL BE
TOMORROW.
FOR SOME REASONS WE WILL
WITHHOLD THAT INFORMATION.
>> WHEN WILL YOU ALLOW PARENTS
TO GO AND GET THE BODIES OF
THEIR CHILDREN.
>> AS SOON AS WE CAN CONFIRM.
WE ARE VERY EARLY INTO THE
INVESTIGATION.
IT'S OBVIOUSLY VERY SENSITIVE
AND WE HAVE TO MAKE SURE WE ARE
RIGHT.
>> FOR MUST BE HORRIBLE AND
BRUTAL FOR PEOPLE WHO ARE WAYING
TO SEE THOSE THEY LOST.
THANK YOU FOR TALKING TO US.
THE STATE POLICE AND WITH THE
NEWTOWN POLICE AS WELL.
YOU CAN IMAGINE THE TONE HERE IS
JUST TERRIBLE AND SO SAD AND
JUST FRAUGHT WITH GRIEF AS WELL.
WE WILL TALK TO PEOPLE WHO SOME
ARE STILL GRAPPLING AND TRYING
TO UNDERSTAND WHAT EXACT EXACTLY
HAPPENED HERE TODAY.
I WANT TO SEND IT BACK TO YOU.
>> I'M NOT SURE IT'S SOMETHING
WE CAN UNDERSTAND.
WE CAN GET AS MANY DETAILS AS WE
CAN.
WE ARE TRYING TO DO THAT WITH AS
MUCH RESPECT FOR THOSE IN
MOURNING AND FOR THAT COMMUNITY
AS POSSIBLE.
IT IS IMPOSSIBLE TO FATHOM WHAT
THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN ARE GOING
THROUGH AND IN PARTICULAR THE
PARENTS AND THE SIBLINGS AND THE
FAMILY MEMBERS OF THE CHILDREN
WHOSE LITTLE LIVES WERE TAKEN
TODAY.
SO MANY LIVES LOST AND SO MANY
MORE LIVES FOREVER CHANGED.
FRIENDS AND NEIGHBORS EVEN
COMPLETE STRANGERS HAVE GATHERED
AND CONTINUE TO AT THIS HOUR TO
HOLD ONE ANOTHER AND CRY AND
PRAY AND TO REMEMBER.
THIS A VIGIL AT A LOCAL CHURCH.
JASON CARROLL JOINS US NOW.
YOU HAVE BEEN OUTSIDE.
WHAT ARE PEOPLE SAYING TO YOU?
WHAT HAS THE MEAD BEEN LIKE?
>> Reporter: HERE AT ST. ROSE
LIMA CHURCH, THE PEOPLE AND THE
HUNDREDS WHO ARE GATHERED
OUTSIDE SIMPLY BECAUSE THERE
WASN'T ENOUGH ROOM INSIDE THE
CHURCH.
THEY ARE STUNNED.
NO OTHER WORD FOR IT.
THEY ARE STUNNED AND HURT.
THEY ARE HERE BECAUSE THEY ARE
LEANING ON EACH OTHER FOR
SUPPORT.
WHEN YOU ARE HURT SO BADLY LIKE
THIS, YOU TURN TO YOUR LOVED
ONES AND FAMILY AND IN SOME
CASES YOU TURN TO YOUR FAITH.
THAT'S WHAT'S HAPPENING OUTSIDE
AS THIS VIGIL CONTINUES THROUGH
THE NIGHT.
IN TALKING TO THE PEOPLE HERE
AND TRYING TO GET TO WHERE WE
WERE, WE PASSED A STARBUCKS.
A WOMAN GOT OUT OF A CAR AND SHE
WAS IN TEARS.
WE WENT BY A RESTAURANT.
A WOMAN WAS OUTSIDE THERE AND
HER HUSBAND AND A YOUNG BOY WERE
VERY UPSET.
AS WE CAME DOWN THE ROAD WHERE
THE CHURCH IS, I SAW A WOMAN WHO
WAS TALKING DOWN THE STREET AND
LOOKED LIKE SHE WAS STUNNED.
COMPLETELY STUNNED.
SHE WAS CRYING AND WANDERING
DOWN THE STREET.
EVEN BEFORE WE GOT CLOSE TO THE
SCENE OF WHERE IT HAPPENED, YOU
KNEW HOW DEEPLY HURT THIS
COMMUNITY WAS BY WHAT HAPPENED.
THAT'S WHAT WE ARE SEEING
OUTSIDE NOW.
THIS IS A CLOSE SKMUNT IT'S NO
SURPRISE THAT THE PEOPLE KNEW
SOME OF THESE PEOPLE AT THE
SCHOOL.
ONE MAN KNEW THE PRINCIPAL, DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG AND HOW MUCH SHE
LOVED THE SCHOOL AND THE
CHILDREN.
I WANT YOU TO LISTEN TO WHAT HE
HAD TO SAY ABOUT HER.
LET ME TELL YOU THAT IN TERMS OF
WHAT HE HAD TO SAY, IT WAS THAT
THIS WAS A WOMAN WHO CARED VERY
DEEPLY NOT JUST ABOUT THE
SCHOOL, BUT SHE WORKED THERE
SINCE JUNE OF 2010 AND SHE CARED
ABOUT THE STUDENTS AND HER JOB.
IT WAS TOUGH FOR HIM TO TAKE AND
THAT'S WHY HE AND SO MANY OTHERS
ARE HERE TONIGHT.
ANDERSON?
>> I KNOW YOU GOT A CHANCE TO
TALK TO THE DEACON IN THE
COMMUNITY AS WELL.
.
>> THAT'S TRUE.
THE DEACON IS HELPING OUT
INDIVIDUALS TONIGHT AND BEFORE
THINGS GOT UNDER WAY.
I SAID WHAT HAVE YOU BEEN DOING
AND HE SAID NEARLY 100 PEOPLE
HAVE COME TO THE CHURCH DOORS SO
FAR LOOKING FOR SUPPORT.
LOOKING FOR COMFORT IN ANY SORT
OF WAY.
HE TALKED ABOUT ONE 6-YEAR-OLD
GIRL WHO HE KNEW WHO WAS KILLED
IN THE SHOOTING AND HOW DEEPLY
THAT HAD AFFECTED HIM.
NOT ONLY IS HE HURT, BUT HE HAS
TO BE THE PILLAR OF STRENGTH AND
PROVIDE STRENGTH WHILE HE IS
TRYING TO HEAL.
ANDERSON?
>> WHAT CAN YOU SAY TO A PARENT
WHO LOST A CHILD?
JASON, THANKS.
AS WORD SPREAD SO DID THE SHOCK
AND THE HORROR AND NOW OF COURSE
THE GRIEVING.
>> YOU CAN NEVER BE PREPARED FOR
THIS KIND OF INCIDENT.
WHAT HAPPENED SKW TRANSPIRED AT
THE SCHOOL BUILDING WILL LEAVE A
MARK ON THIS COMMUNITY AND EVERY
FAMILY IMPACTED.
I ONLY ASK THAT OUR FELLOW
CITIZENS HERE AND AROUND THE
WORLD WHO OFFERED THEIR
ASSISTANCE REMEMBER ALL OF THE
VICTIMS IN THEIR PRAYERS.
>> HIS MAIN RESPONSE IS THE
INVESTIGATION WITH LOCAL
AUTHORITIES.
WE ARE ECHL SIGHING WE DO NOT
WANT TO GIVE UNDUE ATTENTION TO
THE KILLER WHO COMMITTED THE
MURDERS AND BE PART OF HELPING
HISTORY REMEMBER HIS NAME.
WE WANT THE VICTIMS TO BE
REMEMBERED.
WE DO BELIEVE IT'S IMPORTANT TO
UNDERSTAND WHATEVER WE CAN ABOUT
THIS PERSON AND THE CRIME.
HOW WE CAME TO THIS POINT.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI IS HANDLING
COVERAGE OF THE INVESTIGATION.
WHAT'S THE LATEST FROM LAW
ENFORCEMENT?
>> WE ARE TRYING TO GET DOWN TO
MORE ABOUT THE SHOOTER.
ADAM LANZA WAS 20 YEARS OLD AND
WE KNOW ACCORDING TO THE SOURCES
HERE'S ARMED WITH THREE GUNS AND
WEARING BLACK BATTLE FATIGUES
AND A MILITARY VEST.
WHERE DID HE GET THE THREE GUNS
AND WHAT KIND WERE THEY?
THEY WERE THREE HAND GUNS, A
GLOCK AND A SIG SAUER AND A BUSH
MASTER.
THIS IS A SEMI AUTOMATIC GUN AND
WE HAVE PHOTOGRAPHS OF THE TYPE
OF WEAPON IT IS.
WE UNDERSTAND FROM OUR SOURCES
THAT THESE GUNS WERE ALL
REGISTERED AND BELONGED TO HIS
MOTHER.
HIS MOTHER WHO WAS ALSO KILLED.
THE MOTHER'S BODY WAS FOUND IN
THE HOUSE, A FAMILY HOME HERE IN
THIS AREA.
WE DON'T KNOW MUCH MORE ABOUT
ADAM LANZA.
WE KNOW THAT HIS BROTHER RYAN
WAS A BIT OLDER AT 24 YEARS OLD.
HE WAS TAKEN IN TO CUSTODY FOR
QUESTIONING.
HE IS NOT CALLED A SUSPECT, BUT
HE WAS IN HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY
WHEN THEY BROUGHT HIM IN FOR
QUESTIONING.
THAT'S WHERE HE LIVES.
THEY WANTED TO TRY TO FIND OUT
WHAT IF ANYTHING HE KNEW AND
WHAT HE COULD TELL THEM ABOUT
HIS BROTHER.
WHAT INFORMATION HE CAN GIVE
ABOUT HIS BACKGROUND AND POLICE
ALSO QUESTIONED THEIR FATHER.
HE STILL LIVES IN THIS AREA.
HE IS DIVORCED FROM HIS WIFE WHO
WAS ONE OF THE VICTIMS HERE AND
REMARRIED.
HE TOO IS BEING QUESTIONED TO
SHED LIGHT ON ADAM LANZA AND WHY
THIS TRAGEDY HAPPENED.
ANDERSON?
>> SUSAN, THANKS VERY MUCH.
WE ARE STARTING TO HEAR
INSPIRING REPORTS ABOUT HOW THE
TEACHERS HANDLED THIS
UNIMAGINABLE TRAUMA.
KAITLYN IS A FIRST GRADE TEACHER
AND RUSHED 15 CHILDREN, 6 AND
7-YEAR-OLDS INTO A SMALL
BATHROOM AND BARRICADED IT WITH
A BOOKSHELF AND SAID THERE WERE
BAD GUYS AND THEY HAD TO WAIT
FOR THE GOOD GUYS.
WHEN THE CHILDREN STARTED
CRYING, SHE WOULD TOLD THE FACES
IN HER HANDS AND SAY IT WAS
GOING TO BE OKAY AND SAID SHOW
ME HER SMILE.
THE KIDS TOLD HER HEART BREAKING
THINGS AND SAID THEY WANTED TO
GO HOME FOR CHRISTMAS AND HUG
THEIR MOMS.
CLEARLY AN EXTRAORDINARY TEACHER
TOLD ABC NEWS WHAT HAPPENED
NEXT.
>> I NEED YOU TO KNOW THAT I
LOVE YOU ALL VERY MUCH.
THAT IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
I THOUGHT THAT WAS THE LAST
THING THEY WERE EVER GOING TO
HEAR AND I THOUGHT WE WERE ALL
GOING TO DIE.
I DON'T KNOW IF THAT'S OKAY.
TEACHERS.
I WANTED THEM TO KNOW SOMEONE
LOVED THEM AND THAT TO BE ONE OF
THE LAST THINGS THEY HEARD.
NOT THE GUNFIRE IN THE HALL WAY.
IT WAS SO HORRIBLE.
>> KAITLYN SAID SHE HEARD THE
GUNFIRE STOP AND WHEN THE POLICE
CAME AND STARTED KNOCKING, SHE
WANTED TO PUT THEIR BADGES UNDER
THE DOOR.
THE TEACHER PROTECTING HER
STUDENTS WITH EVERYTHING SHE
HAD.
TWEET ME ABOUT THIS.
I WILL BE TWEETING AS WELL.
EVEN THOUGH NOTHING CAN EXPLAIN
THIS, A SEARCH FOR MOTIVE AND
REMEMBERING THE FALLEN INCLUDING
SANDY HOOKS'S PRINCIPAL WHO IN
ADDITION HER JOB WAS RAISING
FIVE CHILDREN OF HER OWN.
Bye!
Santa, we made a video for
your trip!
Yeah, you can watch it on your
sleigh!
OK!
Here you go.
Aw, thanks elves.
I also made you a video.
You are so sweet.
But you probably shouldn't watch
it on the sleigh.
Say goodbye to Santa boys!
Bye!
Good bye Santa!
Share videos instantly
with S Beam on the
Galaxy S3 and Note 2.
Available at Best Buy and
Best Buy mobile stores.
>>> IT DOESN'T SEEM LIKE IT'S
EVEN POSSIBLE.
YOU READ IT IN THE PAPER OR SEE
IT IN THE NEWS AND YOU ARE LIKE
OH, MY GOD, THAT POOR FAMILY AND
SOMETHING HAPPENS SO CLOSE TO
HOME.
IT'S LIKE I THINK I'M STILL IN
SHOCK TO BE HONEST.
>> A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE FEELING
THE SAME TONIGHT.
ALL-AROUND THE WORLD.
THE MASSACRE IN SANDY HOOK IS
THE DEADLIEST SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
AMERICAN HISTORY AND ALL THE
WORDS SPOKEN AND I'M SPEAKING
TONIGHT AND WILL SPEAK LATER
TONIGHT ALL SOUND SO SMALL IN
THE FACE OF THIS HORROR.
20 CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS WERE
ALIVE LAST NIGHT GETTING READY
FOR A DAY OF SCHOOL AND TONIGHT
THEY ARE GONE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SPOKE TO THE
NATION EARLIER AND WE PLAYED
SOME OF HIS COMMENTS AND WE
THINK IT'S WORTH HEARING ALL OF
WHAT HE SAID.
>> THIS AFTERNOON I SPOKE TO
GOVERNOR MALLOY AND FBI DIRECTOR
MULLER.
I OFFERED MY CONDOLENCES ON
BEHALF OF THE NATION AND MADE IT
CLEAR HE WILL HAVE EVERY SINGLE
RESOURCE HE NEEDS TO INVESTIGATE
THE HEINOUS CRIME, CARE FOR THE
VICTIMS, COUNSEL THEIR FAMILIES.
WE HAVE ENDURED TOO MANY OF
THESE TRAGEDIES IN THE PAST FEW
YEARS AND EACH TIME I LEARN THE
NEWS, I REACT NOT AS A
PRESIDENT, BUT AS ANYBODY ELSE
WOULD.
AS A PARENT.
THAT WAS ESPECIALLY TRUE TODAY.
I KNOW THERE IS NOT A PARENT IN
AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS, MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES TO HELPING
OUR CHILDREN FULFILL THEIR
DREAMS.
SO OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN TODAY.
FOR THE PARENTS AND
GRANDPARENTS, SISTERS AND
BROTHERS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN AND FOR THE FAMILIES OF
THE ADULTS WHO WERE LOST.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN FOR THE
PARENTS OF THE SURVIVORS AS
WELL.
FOR AS BLESSED AS THEY ARE TO
HAVE THEIR CHILDREN HOME
TONIGHT, THEY KNOW THAT THEIR
CHILDREN'S INNOCENCE HAS BEEN
TORN AWAY FROM THEM TOO EARLY
AND FLOWER NO WORDS THAT WILL
EASE THEIR PAIN.
AS A COUNTRY WE HAVE BEEN
THROUGH THIS TOO MANY TIMES.
WHETHER IT'S AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN OR A SHOPPING
MALL IN OREGON.
OR A TEMPLE IN WISCONSIN OR A
MOVIE THEATER IN AURORA OR A
STREET CORNER IN CHICAGO.
THESE NEIGHBORHOODS ARE OUR
NEIGHBORHOODS.
THESE CHILDREN ARE OUR CHILDREN.
WE WILL HAVE TO COMING TO AND
TAKE MEANINGFUL ACTION TO
PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE
REGARDLESS OF THE POLITICS.
THIS EVENING MICHELLE AND I WILL
DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT IN
AMERICA WILL DO WHICH IS HUG OUR
CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER AND
WILL TELL THEM WE LOVE THEM.
AND WE WILL REMIND EACH OTHER
HOW DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
FAMILIES IN CONNECTICUT CANNOT
DO THAT TONIGHT.
THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT NOW.
IN OUR DAYS TO COME, THAT
COMMUNITY NEEDS US TO BE AT OUR
BEST AS AMERICANS AND I WILL DO
EVERYTHING IN MY POWER AS
PRESIDENT TO HELP.
BECAUSE NOTHING CAN FILL THE
SPACE OF A LOST CHILD OR LOVED
ONE, ALL OF US CAN EXTEND A HAND
TO THOSE IN NEED TO REMIND THEM
THAT WE ARE THERE FOR THEM AND
THAT WE ARE PRAYING FOR THEM AND
THAT THE LOVE THEY FELT FOR
THOSE THEY LOST ENDURES NOT JUST
IN THEIR MEMORIES, BUT ALSO IN
OURS.
MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF THE
VICTIMS AND IN THE WORDS OF
SCRIPTURE, HEAL THE
BROKENHEARTED AND BIND UP THEIR
WOUNDS.
>> POLICE HAVE NOT RELEASED THE
NAMES OF THE VICTIMS.
THE CHILDREN'S LITTLE BODIES
STILL INSIDE THAT SCHOOL AND THE
PARENTS HAVE NOT BEEN ABLE TO
SEE THEM YET.
AS WE LEARN WHO THEY ARE, WHEN
IT'S APPROPRIATE WE WILL FOCUS
ON THEIR LIVES AND THEIR MEMORY.
AS THE VICTIMS, WE WANT HISTORY
TO REMEMBER AND HONOR.
THE SCHOOL'S PRINCIPAL AND
PSYCHOLOGISTS ARE AMONG THE
DEAD.
HERE'S WHAT WE LEARNED ABOUT
BOTH WOMEN.
47-YEAR-OLD DAWN HOCHSPRUNG,
JASON CARROLL MENTIONED HER.
SHE BECAME THE PRINCIPAL BACK IN
2010.
SHE ARRIVED WITH 12 YEARS OF
EXPERIENCE AS A SCHOOL
ADMINISTRATOR AND SHE WAS
RAISING TWO DAUGHTERS AND THREE
STEPDAUGHTERS.
THOSE WHO WORKED WITH HOCHSPRUNG
SAID SHE WAS PASSIONATE ABOUT
HER JOB AND EXPERT ON
CURRICULUM, BUT FUN, BUT FIRM
LEADER.
ONE FRIEND SAID SHE WAS THE KIND
OF PERSON YOU WANT TO BE
EDUCATING YOUR KIDS AND THE KIDS
LOVED HER.
LITTLE KIDS KNOW WHEN SOMEONE
CARES ABOUT THEM AND THAT WAS
HER.
SHE WAS WRITE BEING HER LOVE OF
READING ON TWITTER AND POSTING
PHOTOS ABOUT EVENTS AND
DEVELOPMENTS AT SANDY HOOK.
SHE TWEETED WELCOME BEING OUR
KINDERS THIS MORNING, 74 NEW
OPPORTUNITIES TO INSPIRE
LIFELONG LEARNING.
SHE WAS APPARENTLY TALKING ABOUT
THE NEW KINDERGARTEN CLASS.
SHE RECENTLY INSTALLED A NEW
SECURITY SYSTEM AT THE SCHOOL
WHEN THE SAFEGUARDS ALL VISITORS
HAD TO RING A DOOR BELL AND WAIT
TO BE BUZZED IN AFTER THE DOORS
LOCKED AT 9:30.
IT IS NOT KNOWN HOW THE GUNMAN
GOT IN.
WE DON'T HAVE PHOTOGRAPHS OF
MARY SHERLOCK.
SHE DIED AS WELL.
SHE WAS A SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST
AND 56 YEARS OLD.
SHE WAS AT THE SCHOOL FOR 18
YEARS AND HELD AN UNDER GRAD
DEGREE IN PSYCHOLOGY AND A
SIX-YEAR PROFESSIONAL DEGREE.
THEY HAVE TWO GROWN DAUGHTERS.
THE OLDEST WORKS AS A HIGH
SCHOOL CHORUS TEACHER.
MA
MARY SHERLOCK, WE WILL REMEMBER
YOU.
SOLEDAD?
>> ANDERSON, I'M WITH CHRISTINE
WILFORD, HER SON IS A SECOND
GRADER AT THE SCHOOL AND SHE HAD
A TERRIFYING DAY.
HOW ARE YOU DOING NOW?
>> IT'S STILL PROCESSING.
IT'S SCARY.
NO WORDS.
>> HOW IS YOUR SON DOING?
ARE YOU ENCOURAGING HIM TO TALK
AND SHARE OR TRYING TO TAKE HIS
MIND OFF THE TERRIBLE THINGS HE
WITNESSED AND EXPERIENCED?
>> WE HAVE DONE A LITTLE BIT OF
EACH.
TRYING TO SPOIL HIM AND TAKE HIS
MIND OFF OF IT AND LET HIM PLAY
PS 3 AND TRYING TO TALK AND
PROCESS WITH HIM.
LETTING THEM KNOW WHEN WE FOUND
OUT ABOUT OTHER CHILDREN THAT HE
KNOWS.
>> YOU GOT AN ELECTRONIC ALERT.
THIS IS THE MOST TERRIFYING
THING.
>> MY HUSBAND AND I WERE SITTING
HERE AND A NEIGHBOR WAS OVER.
WE GOT A ROBO CALL THAT ALL
SCHOOLS WERE IN LOCKDOWN DUE TO
A REPORTED SHOOTING.
WE IMMEDIATELY GOT ONLINE AND MY
NEIGHBOR CALLED HER HUSBAND WHO
SAID HE HEARD IT WAS SANDY HOOK
AND WE SAW IT ONLINE AND HOPPED
IN THE CAR AND HEADED TO THE
SCHOOL.
>> THE SCHOOL WAS ON LOCKDOWN.
WHAT EXACTLY DOES THAT MEAN?
>> I'M NOT SURE COMPLETELY WHAT
IT MEANS.
WHEN I GOT THERE ALL OF THE
CHILDREN THAT HAD BEEN EVACUATED
IN THE FIREHOUSE.
>> HOW IS YOUR SON DOING AND HOW
ARE THE KIDS HOLDING UP?
>> IT VARIED.
MY SON SEEMED TO BE OKAY.
HE SAID MOM, I'M OKAY AND I'M
SAFE.
HE GAVE ME A HUG AND A LOT OF
CHILDREN WERE CRYING AND SCARED.
>> WHAT DID HE DESCRIBE HAD
HAPPENED?
>> HE SAID HE HEARD WHAT SOUNDED
LIKE LARGE PANS FALLING.
LOUD NOISES.
HE SAID HIS TEACHER STEPPED
OUTSIDE THE CLASSROOM AND CAME
BACK IN AND LOCKED THE DOOR.
HE HAD THEM START READING
QUIETLY.
>> HOW MUCH TIME WENT BY BETWEEN
WHEN THAT HAPPENED AND WHEN HE
GOT TO YOU?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
HE IS NOT ABLE TO PIECE HOW MUCH
TIME ACTUALLY PASSED.
HE JUST SAID AFTER A LITTLE
WHILE A POLICE OFFICER CAME AND
TOOK THEM OUT OF THE BUILDING
AND BROUGHT THEM TO THE
FIREHOUSE.
>> WE KNOW THAT THE PRINCIPAL
HAD INSTALLED A SYSTEM WHERE YOU
HAVE TO BE BUZZED IN.
>> YES.
IT'S BEEN THAT WAY FOR THE TWO
YEARS WE HAVE BEEN HERE.
YOU HAD TO RING A DOOR BELL AND
BE LET IN.
THE OFFICE IS RIGHT IN FRONT OF
THOSE DOORS.
THEY CAN LOOK OUT AND SEE WHO IS
AT THE DOOR.
>> WAS THERE A REASON FOR THAT.
IT'S TYPICAL IN BIG CITIES, BUT
COMMUNITIES THAT ARE RURAL, IT'S
A LITTLE BIT OF A RARITY.
>> IT'S JUST THE SAFETY OF OUR
CHILDREN IS TAKEN VERY
SERIOUSLY.
IT'S A FAIRLY LARGE SCHOOL
BETWEEN 500 AND 600 STUDENTS
THERE.
THEY WANT TO KEEP CONTROL AND
KNOW WHO IS IN THE BUILDING WITH
OUR CHILDREN.
>> I WAS TALKING TO THE STATE
POLICE AND THEY SAID THAT THEY
WERE PROCESSING THE SCENE AND
CHILDREN WERE STILL INSIDE.
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN TO THEIR SON
WHAP ABOUT HIS CLASSMATE?
>> WE ARE A FAIRLY RELIGIOUS
FAMILY AND WE JUST TALKED ABOUT
THAT THEY HAVE GONE TO HEAVEN.
TO BE WITH JESUS AND THAT'S
ABOUT ALL WE CAN SAY.
WE TALK ABOUT YOU ARE NOT GOING
TO SEE THEM ANYMORE AND THEY ARE
NOT GOING TO BE AROUND.
YOU REALLY JUST STRUGGLE TO FIND
THE WORDS.
>> YOU SHOULD KNOW EVERYONE IS
SENG WELL WISHES NOT JUST TO
YOU, BUT YOUR COMMUNITY AS A
WHOLE.
SO MANY PEOPLE ASKED ME TO PASS
THAT ALONG.
>> WE ARE A STRONG COMMUNITY.
IT IS STRONG FAMILY COMMUNITY
WITH A LOT OF LOVE.
WE WILL GET THROUGH IT SOMEHOW,
SOME WAY.
>> LET'S GO BACK TO ANDERSON.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
MORE NOW ON SANDY HOOK'S
PRINCIPAL.
WE JUST TOLD YOU ABOUT HER A
SHORT TIME AGO.
SHE IS A PROFESSOR AT SAGE
GRADUATE SCHOOL.
DAWN WAS ONE OF HER STUDENTS.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT DAWN.
YOU KNEW HER.
WHAT WAS SHE LIKE?
>> I HAVE KNOWN DAWN FOR THE
PAST SEVERAL MONTHS.
THIS IS THE FIRST COURSE SHE
TOOK IN THE DOCTORAL PROGRAM.
SHE WAS A PERSON WHO LOVED THE
WORK SHE DID.
THE COURSE THAT WE ARE DOING IS
ON LEADERSHIP.
SHE LOVED LEADING CHILDREN TO
THEIR FUTURES.
SHE HAD GREAT POTENTIAL TO TON
MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
A LOT OF OUR COURSE IS ABOUT
COURAGE.
WE READ THAT AND THIS MORNING I
READ ONE OF THE PAPERS THAT SHE
COMMITTED A FEW DAYS AGO.
IT WAS REFERENCING OVERCOMING
FEAR.
IT HAS BEEN AN EXAMPLE OF FACING
FEAR IN THE ULTIMATE SITUATION.
>> WHEN YOU READ THAT PAPER THIS
MORNING, DID YOU KNOW WHAT
HAPPENED?
I WAS IN THE PROCESS OF GREATING
PAPERS AND TOOK A BREAK.
I HEARD ABOUT IT.
THEN WENT BACK TO THE PAPERS AND
IF THISSY QUOTE FROM HER WORK
JUST POPPED AT ME.
SHE WAS ACTUALLY IN THIS PAPER
SPEAKING ABOUT OVERCOMING FEAR.
FACING ONE'S FEAR AND ACTING IN
SPITE OF FEAR.
I APPRECIATE YOU BEING WITH US.
WE ARE TRYING TO FOCUS ON THE
VICTIMS AND LIMITING THE USE OF
THE KILLER'S NAME.
WE DON'T WANT TO REPEAT IT OVER
AND OVER.
I DON'T WANT TO GIVE
ENCOURAGEMENT TO ANYONE ELSY
THAT THEY CAN BE FAMOUS THROUGH
MURDER.
WE ARE TRYING TO LEARN WHAT WE
CAN AS TO WHAT LED THIS PERSON
TO MURDER.
WHAT ARE WE LEARNING?
>> HAVING COVERED SO MANY OF
THESE, IT IS PLAYING OUGHT
ALMOST IN A SICKENING ROUTINE.
A SHOOTER WITH POSSIBLE MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES AND A FAMILY
TRYING TO DEAL WITH THOSE
ISSUES.
POWERFUL GUNS EASILY ACCESSED
AND THE OUTBURST OF VIOLENCE.
THE 20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER
BEGINNING TO PLAY OUT EXACTLY IN
THAT ORDER.
HERE'S WHAT WE DO KNOW.
THE SHOOTER HAD AN OLDER BROTHER
THAT REPORTEDLY TOLD US THAT THE
SHOOTER HAD A PERSONALITY
DISORDER.
HE MENTIONED AUTISM.
CNN HEARD THE SAME INFORMATION
FROM A MAN WHO CALLED HIMSELF A
FRIEND OF THE SHOOTER IN NEWTOWN
WHERE THE SHOOTER LIVED AND HIS
MOTHER TAUGHT SCHOOL.
WE CAN CONFIRM THE GUN SUSAN
TOLD YOU ABOUT, THE TWO HAND
GUNS, THE SEMI AUTOMATIC RIFLE
WAS LEGALLY OWNED BY THE
SHOOTER'S MOTHER NOW DECEASED.
AS WAS STANDARD, PEOPLE ARE
SHOCKED THAT THE PARTICULAR
SHOOTER COULD HAVE BEEN INVOLVED
IN ANYTHING AS IS WITH THE CASE
OF ONE OF THE SHOOTER'S FORMER
CLASSMATES AND SCHOOL BUS
DRIVER.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> JUST A KID.
>> JUST A KID?
>> NEVER ANTISOCIAL?
>> NO.
>> TROUBLE MAKER?
>> NO, DEFINITELY NOT.
>> NOTICEABLE?
DID HE BLEND INTO THE
BACKGROUND?
>> YEAH.
NOTHING THAT WOULD WARRANT ANY
OF THIS.
>> HE WENT AFTER HIS MOM AND
CLASS OF KIDS.
CAN YOU WRAP YOUR MIND ABOUT
THAT?
>> NO, I CANNOT.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT WOULD DO
ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
>> YOUR GENERAL SENSE IS WHAT?
>> THIS IS UNSPEAKABLE.
I FIRST HEARD ABOUT IT -- I'M
STILL IN SHOCK.
EXCUSE ME A MOMENT.
I WANT TO GO.
>> HE WAS A NICE KID.
VERY POLITE.
SHE RAISED VERY NICE BOYS TO ME.
THAT'S WHY I THINK IT'S A SHOCK
TO EVEN KNOW THEM AND REALIZE
WHO THEY ARE AND WHO HE DID.
YOU CAN'T UNDERSTAND WHAT
HAPPENED.
THAT HE SNAPPED.
HE TOOK SUCH INNOCENT LIVES.
>> SO ANDERSON, WHAT CAN WE
EXPECT AS WE LEARNED IN THE CASE
OF THE VIRGINIA TECH SHOOTING
AND SHOOTING OF CONGRESSWOMAN
GABBY GIFFORDS.
THIS YEAR'S MASS KILLING AT THE
MOVIE THEATER IN AURORA.
EXPECT TO SEE IN HINDSIGHT,
MULTIPLE WARNING SIGNS MAY BE
DANGEROUS AND IGNORED AND
PRACTICE SESSION, OBSESSIONS
THAT WERE NOT TAKEN SERIOUSLY OR
THE FAMILY DIDN'T KNOW HOW TO
HANDLE IT.
IN THE END THEY WILL NEVER HAVE
AN ANSWER OR EXPLANATION THAT IS
GOOD ENOUGH FOR THE VICTIM'S
FAMILIES.
IT IS JUST SO SENSELESS.
ANDERSON?
>> ALWAYS MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES
THAT WE ARE STARTING TO HEAR
ABOUT AS WE POINTED OUT.
SO OFTEN IT'S HARD FOR PARENTS
TO GET HELP EVEN IF THEY KNOW
THEIR CHILD HAS A PROBLEM
BECAUSE OF LAWS ON THE BOOKS.
ONE OF THE THINGS WE WILL BE
LOOKING AT.
GUN LAWS, YOU WERE SAYING ALL
THE GUNS WERE LEGALLY ACQUIRED.
CONNECTICUT HAS SOME OF THE
TOUGHEST GUN LAWS THERE.
>> ALREADY CALLS FOR WE NEED TO
STRENGTHEN THE GUN LAWS, BUT
PEOPLE NEED TO LOOK AT WHAT THE
GUN LAWS ARE.
THEY ARE VERY, VERY STRICT,
ANDERSON.
IT'S WHAT LED THEM TO KNOW THE
REGISTRATION OF THE GUNS.
CONNECTICUT HAS THEIR OWN
REGISTRY.
THE HAND GUNS, YOU HAVE TO HAVE
A CERTIFICATE TO POSSESS THOSE
GUNS AND THAT GOES ALONG WITH
WITH A CLASS YOU HAVE TO TAKE
AND YOU HAVE TO BE OVER 21
YEARS.
IF THAT RIFLE WAS AN ASSAULT
RIFLE, MANY PEOPLE CAN KNOW THAT
CONNECTICUT BANS ASSAULT RIFLES.
THE ONES THAT WERE LEGALLY
POSSESSED WERE GRANDFATHERED IN,
BUT THOSE TWO WOULD NEED TO BE
REGISTERED WITH THE STATE.
AS WE KNOW, THESE GUNS WERE
REGISTERED WITH THE MOTHER OF
THE SHOOTER.
>> APPRECIATE THE REPORTING AS
WELL.
WITH US NOW IS DENISE.
HER SECOND GRADER WAS IN SCHOOL
THIS MORNING.
I CANNOT IMAGINE WHAT THIS DAY
HAS BEEN LIKE FOR YOU AND YOUR
CHILD.
HOW IS YOUR CHILD AND HOW ARE
YOU DOING?
>> I THINK EVERYONE IS COPING AS
BEST AS THEY POSSIBLY CAN.
IT'S SHOCKING WHEN IT HAPPENS
ANYWHERE.
WE ARE ALL TRYING TO WRAP OUR
ARMS AROUND THE SITUATION AS
BEST AS WE CAN.
>> DOES YOUR DAUGHTER WANT TO
TALK ABOUT IT WITH YOU OR ARE
YOU ENCOURAGING HER TO OR HOW
ARE YOU HANDLING THIS?
A LOT OF PARENTS AROUND THE
WORLD ARE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT TO SAY TO THEIR CHILD.
>> YOU KNOW, THE HARD THING FOR
ME IS I'M A NEW YORKER AND I
GUESS I'M ACCUSTOMED TO
MANHATTAN AND ALWAYS TELLING ME
KIDS TO BE CAREFUL.
I GUESS YOU NEVER EXPECT IT TO
HAPPEN IN YOUR SCHOOL.
AT THE END OF THE DAY, YOU JUST
LET HER TALK.
SHE MENTIONED QUITE A BIT ABOUT
THE PRINCIPAL WHO MANY OF US
WORKED WITH.
I WORKED WITH HER PERSONALLY
WITH MY BUSINESS.
THAT IS ONE PERSON I KNOW WE
LOST ON A PERSONAL LEVEL.
I KNOW THEY ARE GOING TO HAVE
THE COUNSELLORS AT THE SCHOOL
TODAY.
THEY WERE ALL WELCOME TO GO
THERE.
IF THEY NEED TO SPEAK TO
SOMEBODY, THEY WILL.
>> HAS YOUR DAUGHTER SAID MUCH
ABOUT WHAT SHE SAW OR HEARD?
>> SHE DID MENTION THAT SHE DID
OF COURSE HEAR GUNSHOTS.
THEY WERE ON THE SAME FLOOR.
HER TEACHER MANAGED TO TAKE TWO
CHILDREN OUT OF THE HALL WAY AND
PULL THEM INTO THE CLASSROOM.
LOCK THE DOOR AND MOVE EVERYBODY
OVER TO THE OTHER SIDE OF THE
ROOM.
IT WAS VERY CONFUSING AS IT
WOULD BE IN ANY OF THESE CASES
TO GO AND PICK UP YOUR CHILD
ONCE WE FIGURED OUT THAT
EVERYTHING WAS DISPATCHED TO
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
I WAS ONE OF THE FIRST PARENTS
THERE ALONG WITH A FRIEND OF
MINE.
WE FIGURED OUT WHAT WAS GOING ON
AND I RAN OVER THERE.
THEY WERE SMART TO GET THEM OUT
OF THE BUILDING AND MOVE THEM
OVER TO THE FIREHOUSE.
YOU CAN SEE THAT MY DAUGHTER'S
TEACHER WAS VISIBLY UPSET AS
WELL AS MANY OF THE CHILDREN
THERE.
SHE DID A VERY HEROIC THING AND
PULLED TWO KIDS OUT OF THE HALL
WAY AND SHOVED THEM IN THE CLASS
AND LOCKED THE DOOR.
THE KIDS ARE GOING TO SUFFER
FROM THIS LIKE EVERYTHING ELSE.
IT'S A PSYCHOLOGICAL EVENT THAT
WILL TAKE TIME FOR HEALING.
AS LONG AS EVERYONE GETS THE
PROPER HELP, IT'S NOT SOMETHING
YOU SHAKE OFF EASILY AND NOT FOR
LITTLE PEOPLE.
WE LOST A LOT OF BABIES TODAY IN
THIS TOWN.
THERE A LOT OF VERY SAD
FAMILIES.
AS EVERYONE CAN THINK, YOU NEVER
THINK IT'S GOING TO HAPPEN, BUT
BASICALLY IT HAPPENS ALL OVER
THE WORLD AT THIS POINT.
WE HAVE TO BE COGNIZANT OF
MENTAL HEALTH AND COG ZANDT OF
GUN CONTROL IN MY EYES.
TO TAKE YOUR CHILDREN TO SCHOOL,
YOU HAVE TO WORRY ABOUT SOMEONE
BLOWING THEM ALL UP.
IT'S VERY, VERY UNFORTUNATE, BUT
UNFORTUNATELY IT'S OUR REALITY
THESE DAYS.
.
>> DENISE, I'M SORRY THAT THAT
REALITY WAS VISITED UPON YOUR
DAUGHTER TODAY AND EVERYBODY
ELSE.
I WISH YOU STRENGTH AND PEACE IN
THE DIFFICULT DAYS AHEAD.
THANK YOU FOR TALKING TONIGHT.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH, ANDERSON.
>> OBVIOUSLY WITNESSING THE
MASSACRE IN THE SCHOOL HAS
BEEN -- HOW CAN YOU SAY
OBVIOUSLY, DEEMLY TRAUMATIC
EXPERIENCE FOR THOSE WHO
SURVIVED AND HEARING ABOUT IT IN
THE UNITED STATES AND AROUND THE
WORLD.
IT CAN BE DIFFICULT TO
UNDERSTAND.
THEY HAVE QUESTIONS AND PARENTS
HAVE QUESTIONS ABOUT WHAT TO
SAY.
WE WILL TALK WITH SANJAY GUPTA
AHEAD.
[ sniffs ] I HAVE A COLD.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
>>> I WAS IN NEW YORK AND MY
WIFE CALLED ME IN HYSTERICS.
I RUSHED HOME AND SHE HEARD SOME
BANGS AND SHE WAS BROUGHT INTO A
BATHROOM.
>> IT WAS FRIGHTENING.
MY HEART STOPPED BEATING AND I
CAN'T EVEN EXPLAIN IT.
>> ONE OF THE MOST HORRIFIC
IMAGES AFTER THE SHOOTING THAT
OCCURRED WAS PARENTS AWAITING IN
THE FIREHOUSE FOR WORD OF THEIR
CHILDREN.
MANY WAITING FOR HOURS AND
FINALLY BEING TOLD THAT IF THEY
HADN'T HAD WORD BY THEN, THEIR
LITTLE ONES WERE LOST.
SO MANY FAMILIES TONIGHT IN DEEP
MOURNING.
UNSPEAKABLE GRIEF.
SOLEDAD IS LIVE ON THE SCENE.
SOLEDAD?
>> Reporter: ANDERSON, THE
GUNMAN'S MOTHER IS A
KINDERGARTEN TEACHER AT THE
SCHOOL FOUND DEAD AT THE FAMILY
HOME NOT FAR FROM WHERE I AM.
ALI IS COVERING THAT PART OF THE
STORY FOR US.
>> Reporter: WE ARE ON THE
STREET WHERE THE SHOOTER LIVED
WITH HIS MOTHER.
THERE IS A LOT OF ACTIVITY
AROUND HERE WHERE THAT POLICE
CAR IS.
NONE HAS ANYTHING TO DO WITH THE
RESIDENTS.
MANY OF THE RESIDENTS WERE ASKED
TO LEAVE EARLIER TODAY WHILE THE
POLICE MADE THIS A CRIME SCENE.
YOU CAN SEE THE YELLOW TAPE.
THE CARS AND THERE WERE A COUPLE
OF REPORTERS HERE A MOMENT AGO.
ALL MEDIA ARE TRYING TO GET TO
THE HOUSE DOWN THERE.
THE POLICE HAVE CLOSED THIS OFF.
THESE ARE LARGE HOUSES AROUND
HERE AND ALL OF THEM HAVE
CHRISTMAS DECORATIONS AND IT'S A
QUIET NEIGHBORHOOD.
NO STREET LIGHTS AT ALL.
ALL THE LIGHTS YOU SEE HERE ARE
FROM THE MEDIA.
NOT A LOT OF NEIGHBORS
RESPONDING AND THE REPORTERS ARE
TRYING TO GET A SENSE OF THE
FAMILY AND WHO THEY WERE.
WE HAVE SEEN PEOPLE LOOKING OUT
THEIR WINDOWS AND THERE FAMILIES
BACK IN.
THERE IS A VERY QUIET
NEIGHBORHOOD.
ABOUT 2 1/2 MILES FROM THE
SCHOOL AND AROUND HERE PEOPLE
WHO DID SPEAK TO THE MEDIA OR
DID COMMENT ON THIS SAID THEY
DIDN'T KNOW THE FAMILY.
THIS IS AN AREA WHERE THEY ARE
NOW COMING TOGETHER IN THEIR
GRIEF AND TRYING TO MAKE SENSE
OF THIS.
THIS IS ABOUT THE MOST UNCOMMON
THING YOU WOULD SEE IN A
NEIGHBORHOOD LIKE THIS.
NO REAL ACTION HERE.
THE POLICE SAID THEY WON'T HAVE
MORE COMMENTS UNTIL 8:00 IN THE
MORNING EASTERN TIME WHICH IS
WHEN THEY MIGHT BE ABLE TO GIVE
A POSITIVE IDENTIFICATION FOR
THE SHOOTER.
THEY HAVEN'T DONE THAT YET.
AT LEAST THERE IS A SENSE THAT
ONCE THEY DO THAT, THEY MAY BE
ABLE TO PUT MORE OF THE PUZZLE
PIECESING TO TOGETHER.
YOU CAN SEE NO LIGHTS AND JUST
THAT POLICE CAR MAKING SURE NO
ONE GOES NEAR THAT HOUSE.
>> THANK YOU FOR THAT UPDATE.
THERE IS ANOTHER TERRIBLE PIECE
OF THE PUZZLE TO TALK ABOUT
TONIGHT.
IT IS THE GUNMAN'S BROTHER WHO
WAS TAKEN IN FOR QUESTIONING IN
HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY.
LIVE FOR US IN HOBOKEN WITH
MORE.
WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT EXACTLY
WHY THE BROTHER WAS TAKEN IN?
>> THERE HAS BEEN A LOT OF
CONFUSION ABOUT THE BROTHER AND
WHY HE WAS TAKEN IN.
HE IS 24 YEARS OLD AND THE
BROTHER LIVES IN AN APARTMENT
BEHIND ME.
A FIVE-STORY BUILDING MADE UP OF
TWO AND THREE-BEDROOM
APARTMENTS.
THEY LED HIM INTO A POLICE CAR
IN HANDCUFFS AND LOOKING DAZED
AND A LITTLE BIT CONFUSED AND
VERY, VERY GLUM WHICH YOU CAN
IMAGINE IS UNDERSTANDABLE GIVEN
THE SITUATION.
NOT CLEAR EXACTLY WHY.
I DID TALK TO A POLICE OFFICER
AS I WAS WALKING ON THE SCENE
WHO SAID THERE WAS THIS NOTION
THAT THE SHOOTING SUSPECT HAD
HIS BROTHER'S ID ON HIM AND
HOLDING HIS BROTHER'S ID FOR
SOME REASON AND THERE MAY HAVE
BEEN INITIAL CONFUSION AND
POLICE TOOK THE BROTHER INTO
CUSTODY AND CNN LEARNED AND WE
HAVE BEEN TALKING TO TWO
ROOMMATES OF THE BROTHER WHO ARE
NOT BELIEVED TO HAVE A
CONNECTION TO THE SUSPECT AT
ALL.
ON THE SCENE WHERE I WAS
EARLIER, IT IS TEAMING WITH LAW
ENFORCEMENT ACTIVITY.
JERSEY CITY POLICE AND A BOMB
SQUAD THAT NEVER REALLY ENTERED
THE BUILDING AND THE FBI.
THEY DID REMOVE SOME COLORS FROM
THE APARTMENT.
APPARENTLY A COMPUTER.
WE ARE NOT SURE IF HE IS STILL
IN CUSTODY OR NOT.
IT HAS BEEN A STRANGE SITUATION.
IT IS VERY, VERY QUIET HERE AND
ALMOST NO LAW ENFORCEMENT
PRESENCE AT ALL.
THAT DOES GIVE YOU A SENSE THAT
THIS IS NO LONGER A HUGE STORY
OF INTEREST IN THE
INVESTIGATION.
SOLEDAD?
>> Reporter: THANKS, JOHN FOR
THAT UPDATE.
BACK TO ANDERSON.
>> SOLEDAD, THANKS.
EVERYONE WHO LIVED THROUGH THE
SHOOTING SAW AND HEARD THINGS
THAT NO ONE EVER SHOULD,
ESPECIALLY KIDS.
AS PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID, THEIR
INNOCENCE WAS TORN AWAY.
A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE WONDERING
HOW THE KIDS CAN BE AFFECTED BY
WHAT THEY WITNESSED.
A LOT OF PEOPLE WANT TO KNOW AS
PARENT WHAT IS TO SAY TO THEIR
KID WHO IS WERE WATCHING OR MAY
HAVE HEARD ABOUT IT.
SANJAY GUPTA JOINS ME NOW.
WHAT DO YOU THINK THE BIGGEST
CONCERNS ARE FOR CHILDREN WHO
WITNESSED THE SHOOTINGS OR WERE
IN THE SCHOOL WHEN THIS
HAPPENED?
>> CHILDREN CAN SUFFER PTSD AS
WELL, POST TRAUMATIC STRESS
DISORDER AND WE DON'T THINK
ABOUT IT AS MUCH.
THIS IS SO UNPRECEDENTED IT'S
HARD TO HAVE ANSWERS.
FOR THE NEXT SEVERAL DAYS, THERE
WILL BE REAL CONCERNS ABOUT
THESE KIDS.
TYPICALLY IT'S SHORT-LIVED.
THAT IS THE GOOD NEWS.
SOMETIMES IT CAN PROCEED TO
NIGHTMARES AND ANXIETY AND
PANIC.
IT'S IMPORTANT TO GET HELP
EARLY.
IF YOU GET HELP EARLY, IT'S MUCH
MORE PREDICTIVE OF HOW THEY DO
IN THE LONG RUN.
THERE A LOT OF STUDIES AND ONE
THING I FOUND INTERESTING AND IT
HAS TO DO WITH TONIGHT.
THAT IS SLEEP.
IF A CHILD IS GETTING SLEEP
TONIGHT, IT TENDS TO BE A
POWERFUL PREDICTOR OF HOW THEY
WILL COPE.
KIDS THAT WILL BE THE MOST
VULNERABLE ARE KIDS WHO ARE
CLOSER TO THE VIOLENCE AND HAD
THINGS GOING ON IN THEIR OWN
HOMES AHEAD OF TIME MAKES THEM
MORE AT RISK.
DON'T FORGET SOMETHING THAT YOU
AND I HAVE TALKED ABOUT.
SURVIVOR'S GUILT.
KIDS WHO ARE ALIVE AND WONDER
WHY THEY ARE.
THAT'S SOMETHING THAT PEOPLE
WILL BE MINDFUL OF.
>> IT'S NOT THE IMMEDIATE TRAUMA
OF HEARING OR WITNESSING THIS,
BUT THE LONG-TERM LOSS OF SOME
OF THE THEIR FRIENDS AND
PLAYMATES AND AT THAT AGE,
THAT'S A HARD THING TO
UNDERSTAND.
ONE OF THE REASONS THAT
COUNSELLORS WILL BE AVAILABLE
STARTING TOMORROW, ARE KIDS MORE
AT RISK OF SUFFERING PTSD THAN
ADULTS?
>> BOTH CAN SUFFER, BUT THE
DIFFERENCE IS THAT WITH CHILDREN
AS YOUNG AS THIS, THEY DON'T
VERBALIZE IT THE SAME WAY.
YOU MAY HAVE DEVELOPMENTAL
DELAYS THAT ARE UNUSUAL.
YOU COULD HAVE REGRESSION
OVERALL AND TEMPER TANTRUMS.
THERE'S THE THINGS THAT MAY NOT
FIT EXACTLY WITH WHAT YOU EXPECT
WITH PTSD, BUT IT CAN BE MORE
VAGUE.
WITH ADULTS, HYPER VIGILANCE AND
QUICK REACTIONS TO THINGS AND
RELIVING THE TRAUMA AND THE
HORROR OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
OBVIOUSLY OF COURSE THE PARENTS
OF THE CHILDREN WHO DIED ARE AT
MOST RISK FROM ALL OF THIS.
>> SANJAY, APPRECIATE IT.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
SantHo, Ho, Ho!anta!
Santa!
Want to see some magic?
Watch this! Merry Chr...
(Crash) Ow!
I landed on my keys.
Did you get that?
Oh yeah.
That was amazing.
Here you go.
That was a fun trick!
See? Santa's okay.
Walk it off Santa.
Share videos instantly
with S Beam.
On the Galaxy SIII
and Note II.
For a limited time get two flip
covers for the price of one.
Exclusively at Verizon.
HOW THEY'LL LIVE TOMORROW.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
.
>> IT FEELS LIKE A NIGHTMARE.
YOU NEVER IN A MILLION YEARS
WOULD THINK YOU DROP YOU'RE
CHILD OFF AT SCHOOL AND HUGS AND
KISSES AND SEE YOU AT THE END OF
THE DAY.
YOU NEVER KNOW.
ARE YOU STILL GOING TO -- 20
MINUTES FROM NOW, YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN.
YOU COUNT YOUR BLESSINGS EVERY
DAY FOR WHAT YOU HAVE.
>> I'M BACK WITH SOLEDAD O'BRIEN
WHO IS LIVE IN CONNECTICUT.
I HAVE BEEN IN THAT TOWN.
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL AREA.
THE LAST PLACE YOU WOULD EXPECT
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
I KNOW YOU HAVE BEEN TALKING TO
A LOT OF FAMILIES.
ASKING HOW THEY ARE DOING SOUNDS
SO HOLLOW, BUT WHAT ARE PEOPLE
SAYING?
>> THEY ARE JUST STUNNED.
PARENTS HAVE COMING AND BRINGING
THEIR KIDS WITH THEM.
THEY ARE STUNNED THAT THEY ARE
SO BLESSED THEY SURVIVED AND
CHILDREN SURVIVE AND THEY WERE
ABLE TO DODGE A TERRIBLE THING
AND YET THEY KNOW SO MANY
FAMILIES IN THE COMMUNITY DID
NOT HAVE CHILDREN WHO SURVIVED.
INSIDE THE SCENE OF LAW
ENFORCEMENT THAT IS BEING
PROCESSED.
THE PARENTS CANNOT BE WITH THEIR
CHILDREN AND CAN NEVER BE.
THERE IS A TERRIBLE HORROR
BEHIND IT ALL.
WHY AND WHAT DROVE THE SHOOTER
TO DO THIS.
SO MANY QUESTIONS NEED TO BE
ANSWERED AND PROBABLY AS LAW
ENFORCEMENT TOLD US WILL BE
ANSWERED, IT JUST TAKES TIME.
IT TAKES INVESTIGATION.
THAT'S ABSOLUTELY NO RELIEF TO
ANYBODY HERE.
>> THE IDEA THAT THE KIDS ARE
STILL IN THERE.
IT'S SUCH A HORRIBLE THING.
I APPRECIATE YOUR SENSITIVE
REPORTING.
WE SAW A LIT OF IT AT THE TOP OF
THE HOUR.
THE VIGIL IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
A COMMUNITY SHATTERED.
THEY CANNOT HOLD ALL THE PEOPLE
WHO WANT TO BE THERE AND SAY
PRAYERS AND ADD THEIR HOPES AND
THEIR REMEMBRANCES FOR THE
FAMILY WHO IS LOST LOVED ONES.
WE ADD TO THAT VIGIL OUR PRAYERS
AND THOUGHTS TO THE PARENTS AND
THE CHILDREN AND FAMILIES AND
FRIENDS.
SO MANY HEARTS ARE WITH YOU
TONIGHT.
>> I WOULD LIKE TO SHARE A
LETTER FROM HIS HOLINESS, POPE
BENEDICT XVI.
I WAS INFORMED OF THE SHOOTING
AT HANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
I CONVEY MY HEART FELT AND
PRAYERS TO THE VICTIMS AND
FAMILIES.
TO ALL OF THOSE IN THE COMMUNITY
OF NEWTOWN AND ESPECIALLY THE
PARISH OF ST. ROSE OF LIMA.
>> I HAVE NO WORDS THAT MAKE THE
PAIN OF WHAT HAPPENED TODAY EASY
TO BEAR.
I AM HEARTBROKEN AS I KNOW ALL
OF YOU ARE.
THERE IS NOTHING MORE HURTFUL
AND TRAGIC THAN THE LOSS OF
INNOCENCE, BUT NO