>>> IT IS 10:00 IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, A COMMUNITY STILL
STRUGGLING WITH GRIEF AND STILL
REACHING OUT TO ONE ANOTHER FOR
COMFORT AND BEGINNING THE LONG
PROCESS OF SAYING GOODBYE TO SO
MANY YOUNG LIVES, LIVES CUT FAR
TOO SHORT.
MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS REMIND THE
PEOPLE OF THIS COMMUNITY THEY
ARE NOT ALONE IN THEIR GRIEF AND
PEOPLE STOP BY TO LEAVE CANDLES
AND FLOWERS AND TEDDY BEARS AND
NOTES OF COMFORT.
IT IS A DAUNTING CONCEPT, THE
IDEA OF TRYING SOMEHOW TO MOVE
ON WITHOUT THE 26 SIX AND
7-YEAR-OLDS THAT LOST THEIR
LIVES FRIDAY AND TRYING TO MOVE
ON WITHOUT THE SIX ADULTS ALSO
KILLED AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
MOVING ON MAY NOT BE POSSIBLE
FOR A VERY LONG TIME IF EVER.
IT IS NOT CLEAR JUST WHEN THE
STUDENTS OF SANDY HOOK WILL
RETURN TO CLASS BUT WHEN THEY
DO, IT WILL BE IN A DIFFERENT
BUILDING, A DIFFERENT SCHOOL, IN
A NEIGHBORING TOWN.
EVERYTHING IS DIFFERENT NOW.
EVERYTHING.
FOR THE FAMILIES HERE THIS WEEK
IS ABOUT TRYING TO FIND A WAY TO
SAY GOODBYE AND TO HONOR THE
LIVES OF THEIR CHILDREN, THE
LIVES OF THEIR TEACHERS AND
SCHOOL ADMINISTRATORS, THEIR
THREE FUNERALS SCHEDULED FOR THE
REST OF THE WEEK FOR THREE
6-YEAR-OLDS AND THERE WERE TWO
FUNERALS TODAY ALSO FOR
6-YEAR-OLDS, JACK PINTO AND NOAH
POZNER.
TONIGHT WE REMEMBER JACK AND
NOAH AND WISH THEIR FAMILIES AND
FRIENDS AND CLASSMATES PEACE AND
STRENGTH AT THIS UNIMAGINABLY
DIFFICULT TIME.
>> IN A TRIBUTE TO THE LITTLE
BOY THAT LOVED SPORTS, TEAMMATE
FROM THE LOCAL YOUTH WRESTLING
ASSOCIATION WORE THEIR UNIFORMS
AND MEDALS TO JACK PINTO'S
FUNERAL.
JACK WAS AN AVID SPORTS FAN, NOT
JUST WREGS LIGHTNING BUT
BASEBALL, BASKETBALL AND SKIING
AND HIS FIRST LOVE WAS FOOTBALL.
HE IDOLIZED THE NEW YORK GIANTS
VICTOR CRUZ THAT PAID TRIBUTE BY
WRITING HIS NAME ON HIS CLEATS
BEFORE A GAME THIS PAST WEEKEND.
ACCORDING TO THE "NEW YORK
TIMES" A FAMILY FRIEND THAT GAVE
A EULOGY AT THE FUNERAL
DESCRIBED HIM AS THE KIND OF BOY
THAT COMMANDED THE ATTENTION IN
THE ROOM AND HE WANTED NOTHING
MORE THAN TO CATCH UP WITH HIS
OLDER BROTHER BEN WHOM HE WOULD
HAVE FOLLOWED ANYWHERE.
IN HIS OWE BITARY JACK'S FAMILY
WROTE IN LIFE AND IN DEATH JACK
WILL FOREVER BE REMEMBERED FOR
THE IMMEASURABLE JOY HE BROUGHT
TO ALL WHO HAD THE PLEASURE OF
KNOWING HIM, A JOY WHOSE WIDE
REACH BELIED HIS SIX SHORT
YEARS.
ALSO LAID TO REST TODAY, NOAH
POZNER, WHO JUST CELEBRATED HIS
SIXTH BIRTHDAY LAST MONTH WITH
HIS TWIN AND BEST FRIEND ARIEL.
THEY WERE BOTH FIRST GRADERS AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY AND ON
FRIDAY ARIEL'S CLASS REPORTEDLY
HID IN A BATHROOM DURING THE
ATTACK.
SHE SURVIVED.
NOAH DID NOT.
>> WE ARE ALL COMPLETELY
SHATTERED.
IT HAS BEEN A VERY, VERY ROUGH
FEW DAYS.
NOBODY IS GETTING MUCH SLEEP.
WE'RE HOLDING TOGETHER AS BEST
WE CAN.
YOU NEVER, EVER THINK THAT
SOMETHING LIKE THIS COULD HAPPEN
TO YOUR FAMILY.
>> NOAH'S AUNT SAYS HE LOVED TO
READ AND FIGURE OUT HOW THINGS
WORKED.
SHE SAID HE WAS EXTREMELY
LIVELY, THE LIGHT OF THE ROOM.
SHE WILL REMEMBER HIS BIG BLUE
EYES, A BOY WITH A BIG HEART,
WHO LOVED HIS PARENTS, HIS OLDER
SISTERS, AND BROTHER AND HIS
TWIN MOST OF ALL.
>> THEY DON'T KNOW THE WAY IN
WHICH NOAH PASSED AWAY, BUT
OBVIOUSLY THEY WERE THERE DURING
THE WHOLE EVENT, AND WERE LET
OUT AND IT IS NOT SOMETHING THAT
SHE JUST TURNED SIX.
SHE JUST IS UNDER SIX, AND THEIR
OLDER SISTER SOPHIA IS NOT QUITE
EIGHT YET AND HOW DO YOU TELL
THEM THAT'S HOW THEIR BROTHER
DIED?
IT IS JUST THE UNTHINKABLE
REALLY.
>> IN HIS OBITUARY HIS FAMILY
SAYS HE WAS IMPISH AND LARGE OF
LIFE AND DEVOID OF MEANNESS.
THEY WROTE EVERYTHING HE DID
CONVEYED ACTION AND ENERGY
THROUGH LOVE.
HE WAS THE LIGHT OF OUR FAMILY.
LE BE FOREVER MISSED.
>> WE HAVE JUST EVEN THE EULOGY
DELIVERED BY HIS MOTHER AT HIS
FUNERAL TODAY PUBLISHED BY THE
"NEW YORK TIMES" AND DISTRIBUTED
BY THE ASSOCIATED PRESS.
I WANT TO READ A PART TO YOU.
ARE YOU A LITTLE BOY WHOSE LIFE
FORCE HAD ALL THE GRAVITATIONAL
PULL OF A IS HE LESSAL BODY.
YOU WERE LIGHT AND LOVE,
MISCHIEF AND FRANKS, YOU ADORED
YOUR FAMILY WITH EVERY FIBER OF
YOUR 6-YEAR-OLD BEING.
WE'RE ALL ELEVATED IN HUMANITY
BY HAVING KNOWN YOU, A LITTLE
MAVERICK THAT DIDN'T ALWAYS WANT
TO DO HIS SCHOOLWORK OR CLEAN UP
HIS TOYS WHEN PRACTICING HIS
NINJA MOVES OR SUPER MARIO ON
THE WII SEEMED FAR MORE
IMPORTANT.
YOU WILL NOT PASS THROUGH THIS
WAY AGAIN.
I CAN ONLY BELIEVE YOU WERE
PLANTED ON EARTH TO BLOOM IN
HEAVEN.
TAKE FLIGHT, MY BOY.
SOAR.
THE WORDS OF A MOTHER GRIEVING
FOR HER LOST SON.
ONE THING THAT WE HAVE BEEN
DOING IS TRYING TO KEEP OUR
FOCUS ON THE LIVES LOST AND THE
LIVES OF THE PEOPLE HERE WHO
DIED LED, THE HEROES THAT SAVED
LIVES AND STOPPED MORE BLOODSHED
AND OFTEN PUT THEMSELVES IN
HARM'S WAY TO DO IT, THE
TEACHERS AND THE SCHOOL
ADMINISTRATORS AND WE HAVE
AVOIDED FOCUSING ON THE KILLER
BECAUSE HE HAS GONE AND FRANKLY
WE DON'T WANT HIM TO BE
REMEMBERED, CERTAINLY NOT HIS
NAME.
WE TRIED TO BE CAREFUL AND
RESPECTFUL OF WHAT THE FAMILIES
HERE ARE GOING THROUGH AND WE
WILL CONTINUE TO DO THAT.
WE TRIED NOT TO INTRUDE ON THEIR
SUFFERING.
AFTER LAST NIGHT'S PROGRAM WE
GOT A CALL FROM THE McDONALD
FAMILY.
THEIR 7-YEAR-OLD, GRACE, AMAZING
GRACE, DIED ON FRIDAY.
I SPOKE WITH GRACE'S PARENTS AT
LENGTH TODAY AND WE'RE GOING TO
BRING YOU THAT INTERVIEW
TOMORROW.
WE WERE GOING TO BRING IT TO YOU
TONIGHT.
WE HAD A TECHNICAL PROBLEM WITH
IT.
WE WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT WE DO
IT RIGHT AND WE BRING YOU THE
COMPLETE INTERVIEW AND SO WE'LL
DO THAT TO YOU.
WE'LL BRING THAT TO YOU
TOMORROW.
TONIGHT WE REMEMBER ALL THE
VICTIMS AND ALSO THE HEROES OF
THIS TRAGEDY, THE TEACHERS THAT
DID SO MUCH TO PROTECT THEIR
STUDENTS AND THE FIRST
RESPONDERS.
HERE IS WHAT LIEUTENANT VANCE OF
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
SAID ABOUT THE FIRST RESPONDERS.
>> THE FACULTY, STAFF IN THAT
SCHOOL DID EVERYTHING THAT THEY
POSSIBLY COULD TO PROTECT THOSE
CHILDREN.
I CAN TELL YOU THAT THE FIRST
RESPONDERS THAT GOT TO THE SCENE
ENTERED THAT SCHOOL AND SAVED
MANY HUMAN LIVES.
I CAN TELL YOU IT BROKE OUR
HEARTS THAT WE COULDN'T SAVE
THEM ALL.
>> LAST NIGHT'S MEMORIAL, THE
FIRST RESPONDERS GOT A STANDING
OVATION FROM A VERY GRATEFUL
COMMUNITY.
ROB AND RAY ARE FIRE FIGHTERS
WITH THE NEWTOWN HOOK AND LADDER
COMPANY AND JOIN ME LIVE.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US.
HOW YOU ARE YOU HOLDING UP.
>> IT IS DIFFICULT EVERY DAY.
EVERY DAY IT IS A LITTLE BETTER,
BUT IT IS A CHALLENGE, CERTAINLY
A CHALLENGE.
>> ONE OF THE THINGS I KNOW
USUAL DOING IS HANDING OUT GIFTS
TO LITTLE KIDS, THINGS FROM THE
RED CROSS.
IT HAS TO BRING SOME COMFORT.
>> DEFINITELY HELPS.
OVERWHELMING AMOUNT OF STUFFED
ANIMALS AND TEDDY BEARS HAVE
BEEN STREAMING INTO THE FIRE
HOUSE AND WE'RE DOING WHAT WE
CAN TO GET IT OUT TO THE
CHILDREN IN TOWN.
>> YOU WERE BORN HERE, RIGHT.
>> YES.
>> TELL PEOPLE ABOUT THIS
COMMUNITY.
I HAVE JUST BEEN STRUCK BY HOW
CLOSE KNIT IT SEEMS AND PROBABLY
NOW MORE THAN EVER.
>> THE OVER POURING OF SUPPORT
FROM PEOPLE IN THE COMMUNITY AND
THE UNITY AND THE EMOTION IS
JUST OVERWHELMING.
I CAN'T SAY ENOUGH OF THE
SUPPORT WE HAVE BEEN GETTING
FROM EVEN OUTSIDE OTHER
COMMUNITIES AND ALL AROUND THE
COUNTRY, THE PHONES RINGING OFF
THE HOOK FOR PEOPLE THAT WANT TO
BRING FOOD OR SUPPLIES OR
WHATEVER THEY CAN.
>> I KNOW ON THAT HORRIBLE DAY
ON FRIDAY YOU GUYS WERE ASSIGNED
TO A TRIAGE AREA.
IT DIDN'T UNFORTUNATELY END UP
BEING USED.
THAT MUST HAVE BEEN JUST A
SICKENING FEELING TO BE THERE AT
THIS TRIAGE UNIT AND REALIZE
THERE IS NOT PEOPLE COMING IN.
>> AT THE TIME A FEW TIMES
DURING THE INCIDENT I ACTUALLY
THOUGHT TO MYSELF SHOULD I BE
HOPING THAT THIS AREA WAS FILLED
WITH INJURED PEOPLE?
I WAS ALMOST WISHING THAT IT
WAS -- THE CASE, FAIRLY EARLY ON
WE REALIZED THAT IT WASN'T GOING
TO BE THE CASE AND IT WAS
BASICALLY SET UP FOR NOTHING.
>> HOW DO YOU DEAL WITH
SOMETHING LIKE THAT AS A FIRST
RESPONDER?
EVERYBODY THINKS ABOUT OBVIOUSLY
THE CHILDREN AND THE TEACHERS
AND ALL OF THOSE WHO LOST THEIR
LIVES AND THE PARENTS, BUT THE
THINGS THAT YOU GUYS HAVE TO
DEAL WITH, THERE IS -- IT NEVER
LEAVES YOU.
>> NO.
NO.
>> HAVE YOU A JOB TO DO AT THE
TIME AND THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE
THINKING ABOUT AT THE TIME.
YOU REALLY DON'T THINK TOO MUCH
ABOUT THAT KIND OF STUFF UNTIL
LATER, AND EVEN NOW THERE IS
STILL A LOT OF STUFF GOING ON
AND I THINK IT WILL GET WORSE
BEFORE IT GETS BETTER.
>> YEAH.
I HAVE ALWAYS FOUND THAT IN THE
FIRST COUPLE OF DAYS AND WHEN
THERE IS A LOT OF FOCUS AND
ATTENTION AND ADRENALINE GETS
YOU THROUGH, BUT IT IS OFTEN IN
THE WEEKS AFTER THAT THE PEOPLE
GO AWAY AND THE REST OF THE
WORLD KEEPS SPINNING AND RETURNS
TO SOME SEMBLANCE OF NORMAL,
THEN IT IS THIS TOWN WHICH WILL
BE LEFT WITH AN OPEN WOUND.
>> THERE IS GOING TO BE A NEW
NORMAL, I THINK.
THE OLD NORMAL A WEEK AGO IS
GONE, I BELIEVE.
>> LIVE IN COMPLACENCY ALL THESE
YEARS AND IT IS GONE.
WE'LL BE SCARRED FOREVER FROM
THIS, I THINK.
>> WE WILL RECOVER OBVIOUSLY.
LIKE ROB SAID, WE'RE WITH A
CLOSE KNIT COMMUNITY AND WE'LL
RECOVER SOMEWHAT, BUT IT IS LIKE
ROB SAID.
THE SCARS ARE NOT GOING TO GO
AWAY.
>> SCARS HEAL BUT REMAIN AND
THEY'RE ALWAYS THERE.
I REALLY APPRECIATE ALL YOU HAVE
DONE AND THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR
TALKING.
I WISH YOU THE BEST
>> THANK YOU.
>> WITH THE COMMUNITY REALLY
UNITED IN GRIEF, ONE PIECE OF
THE PLAN TO MOVE BEYOND THE
TRAGEDY IS TAKING SHAPE TODAY,
AND WHEN I SAY MOVE BEYOND, I
DON'T WANT TO MAKE IT SOUND LIKE
PEOPLE WANT TO FORGET BECAUSE
THEY DON'T.
THIS TOWN WILL NEVER FORGET AND
THEY JUST NEED TO TRY TO FIGURE
OUT A WAY TO CONTINUE ON AND
HONOR THE MEMORY OF THOSE WHO
THEY HAVE LOST.
HOW NEWTOWN'S NEIGHBORS ARE
HELPING SANDY HOOK STUDENTS FEEL
SAFE WHEN THEY RETURN TO CLASS,
I WILL SPEAK TO THOSE THAT LOST
LOVED ONES IN PREVIOUS MASS
SHOOTINGS ABOUT THEIR HEALING
PROCESS.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
♪ OOH BABY, LOOKS LIKE
YOU NEED A LITTLE HELP THERE ♪
♪ OOH BABY,
CAN I DO FOR YOU TODAY? ♪
[ Female Announcer ] NEED HELP
KEEPING YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE?
ALIGN CAN HELP.
ONLY ALIGN HAS BIFANTIS,
A PATENTED PROBIOTIC
THAT NATURALLY HELPS MAINTAIN
YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE.
TRY ALIGN TO HELP RETAIN
A BALANCED DIGESTIVE SYSTEM.
TRY THE #1 GASTROENTEROLOGIST
RECOMMENDED PROBIOTIC.
ALIGN.
>>> WELL, NEWTOWN SCHOOLS WILL
REOPEN TOMORROW, BUT NOT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY, OBVIOUSLY.
INSTEAD ANOTHER, A FORMER SCHOOL
WILL REOPEN EVENTUALLY FOR THE
STUDENTS WHO SURVIVED THE
SHOOTING.
THE MOVE WILL ALLOW SANDY HOOK
STUDENTS TO RETURN TO CLASS
WITHOUT HAVING TO RETURN TO THE
SITE OF THE TRAGEDY.
CONNECTICUT'S GOVERNOR DAN
MALLOY ANNOUNCED THE MOVE TODAY
AT A VERY EMOTIONAL NEWS
CONFERENCE, WHERE HE ALSO
RECOUNTED THE MOMENTS AFTER THE
SHOOTING WHEN HE NEEDED TO
DELIVER TO THE PARENTS WHO WERE
WAITING FOR NEWS ABOUT THEIR
CHILDREN, WHEN HE NEEDED TO
DELIVER THE WORST POSSIBLE NEWS.
>> IT WAS EVIDENT TO ME THAT
THERE WAS A RELUCTANCE TO TELL
PARENTS AND LOVED ONES THAT THE
PERSON THAT THEY WERE WAITING
FOR NOT GOING TO RETURN.
AND THAT HAD GONE ON FOR A
PERIOD OF TIME, WELL AFTER THERE
WAS ANY EXPECTANCY THAT FAMILIES
WOULD BE REUNITED.
I MADE THE DECISION THAT TO HAVE
THAT GO ON ANY LONGER WAS WRONG.
SO I DID IT.
>> I TALKED TO LYNN McDONNELL.
KATE BALDWIN JOINS ME NOW.
I TALKED TO LYNN McDONNELL
EARLIER.
WE'RE GOING TO PLAY THE FULL
INTERVIEW TOMORROW.
I TALKED TO HER AND HER HUSBAND
CHRIS ABOUT THAT WAIT.
THEY THOUGHT MAYBE THEIR LITTLE
GRACE WAS IN SOME PLACE THAT WAS
SAFE.
AND THEN SLOWLY IT BEGAN TO DAWN
ON PEOPLE THAT THAT WAS NOT THE
CASE.
SO WHAT ARE THE PLANS NOW FOR
SCHOOLS?
>> IT REALLY STARTED KICKING
INTO ACTION THE SAME DAY AS THE
HORROR WAS UNFOLDING.
NO ONE WANTS TO SEND THE
CHILDREN BACK TO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
THEY KNOW THAT IT'S CLEARLY NOT
TIME FOR THAT.
IT'S STILL A CRIME SCENE RIGHT
NOW.
SO THEY MADE PLANS WITH THE
NEIGHBORING TOWN FOR A SCHOOL
JUST SIX MILES AWAY.
ALMOST -- IT'S VERY FORTUITOUS.
BUT THERE WAS AN EMPTY MIDDLE
THAT HAD BEEN CLOSED BECAUSE OF
DECLINING ENROLLMENT LAST YEAR.
SO THE NEIGHBORING TOWN MONROE,
THE CHIEF EXECUTIVE OF THE TOWN,
HE CALLED THEM RIGHT AWAY THAT
SAME DAY AND SAID IF YOU WANT
IT, IT'S YOURS.
AND SO THEY'VE BEEN WORKING
AROUND THE CLOCK.
CONTRACTORS FROM AROUND THE
REGION HAVE BEEN DONATING THEIR
TIME TO GET THIS FACILITY, IT'S
A FORMER MIDDLE SCHOOL UP TO
SNUFF AND UP TO CODE.
THEY HAVE TO CHANGE, REALLY,
EVERYTHING.
THE BONES ARE STRONG.
IT'S A SCHOOL.
BUT THEY HAVE TO LOWER
EVERYTHING.
THEY HAVE TO REPLACE TOILETS TO
BE SMALL ENOUGH FOR CHILDREN,
FOR ELEMENTARY SCHOOL CHILDREN.
THEY HAVE TO LOWER TOWEL
DISPENSERS.
>> DO YOU KNOW WHEN THE KIDS ARE
GOING TO GO BACK?
>> THAT'S UP TO TOWN OFFICIALS.
THE MONROE TOWN OFFICIALS TOLD
ME TODAY THE BUILDING ITSELF
COULD BE READY AS EARLY AS
TOMORROW.
THEY'VE BEEN WORKING AROUND THE
CLOCK TO GET IT READY.
BUT WHEN THE SCHOOL SYSTEM IS
READY TO ASK THE CHILDREN TO
COME BACK TO SCHOOL, THAT'S UP
TO NEWTOWN SCHOOL OFFICIALS.
AND THIS FRIDAY IS SUPPOSED TO
BE THE LAST DAY OF SCHOOL BEFORE
THE HOLIDAY BREAK.
SO IT COULD BE, YOU KNOW, ONLY A
DAY OR TWO THAT THEY'LL BE IN
CLASS.
BUT SOME ARE SAYING, WE ACTUALLY
TALKED ABOUT IT WITH SANJAY
EARLIER, SOME ARE SAYING THAT'S
REALLY WHAT THE KIDS NEED TO DO.
THEY NEED TO GET BACK INTO THAT
ROUTINE.
BECAUSE ONCE THEY GET INTO THAT
ROUTINE AND BACK INTO SCHOOL AND
BACK FOCUSING ON THEIR SCHOOL
AND WORK, THAT'S GOING TO HELP
THEM HEAL FASTER.
>> AND OF COURSE THERE ARE GOING
TO BE A NUMBER OF FUNERALS ALL
THIS WEEK.
>> YES.
>> WE SAW TWO TODAY.
I KNOW GRACE McDONNELL, THAT THE
WAKE IS ON THURSDAY.
I THINK THE FUNERAL IS GOING TO
BE ON FRIDAY.
SO WHETHER THE KIDS ARE GOING TO
GO TO FUNERALS OBVIOUSLY, AND
OBVIOUSLY THEY'RE GOING TO NEED
TO HAVE COUNSELORS ON SCENE.
THAT FIRST DAY FOR THE KIDS COME
BACK TO THAT SCHOOL.
>> SO TOUGH.
AND I'VE BEEN TOLD THEY'RE EVEN
TALKING TO TEACHERS ABOUT HOW TO
TALK TO STUDENTS ON THE FIRST
DAY BACK.
>> SURE.
>> IF THERE ARE QUESTIONS, IF
VIOLENCE IS BROUGHT UP OR
WHATEVER QUESTIONS MAY COME UP.
YOU KNOW, CHILDREN SEE AND KNOW
MORE THAN THEY GIVE OFF, YOU
KNOW.
THEY'RE VERY PERCEPTIVE,
ESPECIALLY AT THAT AGE.
THEY'VE BEEN WORKING WITH
TEACHERS, AND WE SAW IT WHEN WE
WERE DRIVING AROUND.
THEY SAID THAT CHALK HILL, THAT
MIDDLE SCHOOL WHERE THE SANDY
HOOK CHILDREN ARE GOING TO BE
GOING, IT WILL LIKELY BE THE
MOST SECURE SCHOOL IN THE STATE.
AND THEY'RE VERY SERIOUS
ABOUT -- THERE IS POLICE PATROL
AT EVERY SCHOOL.
THEY SAID UNFORTUNATELY THAT MAY
NOW BE THE NEW NORMAL AS THEY'RE
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHAT TO DO
AND HOW TO PROTECT THEIR KIDS.
>> KATE, I APPRECIATE THAT
THANKS FOR ALL THAT LATEST
INFORMATION.
SADLY, THIS IS NOW THE LATEST
MASS SHOOTING TO BRING THE
COUNTRY TOGETHER IN GRIEF.
AND WHILE MANY AMERICANS ARE
STILL STRUGGLING TO GRASP THE
ENORMITY OF WHAT HAPPENED IN
NEWTOWN, OTHER FAMILIES ALREADY
KNOW WHAT IT'S LIKE TO FACE THIS
SORT OF NIGHTMARE.
WE THOUGHT IT WORTHWHILE TO TALK
TO SOME OF THE PEOPLE WHO HAVE
BEEN THROUGH THIS KIND OF A
TRAGEDY BEFORE.
AND SADLY, THERE ARE MANY OF
THEM.
AMARDEEP KALEKA LOST HIS FATHER
AT THE SIKH TEMPLE SHOOTING IN
OAK CREEK, WISCONSIN IN
AUGUST.
WE TALKED TO AMARDEEP A LOT.
AND ROXANA GREEN LOST THEY ARE
DAUGHTER CHRISTINA TAYLOR GREEN
IN THE SHOOTING IN TUCSON,
ARIZONA, THAT
ALSO INJURED GABBY GIFFORDS
NEARLY TWO YEARS AGO.
ROXANNA GREEN IS JOINING ME NOW.
AND AMARDEEP IS GOING TO BE
JOINING ME IN JUST A MOMENT.
ROXANNA, WHEN YOU HEARD THE
NEWS, WHAT WAS YOUR REACTION?
IT MUST JUST ALL BRING IT BACK.
>> I WAS DEVASTATED.
I WAS HEARTBROKEN FOR ALL THE
FAMILIES AND THE VICTIMS.
IT JUST BROUGHT IT ALL BACK TO
ME, AND I WAS VERY, VERY SAD.
>> LET ME JUST GIVE YOU A MIC
BECAUSE I THINK WE'RE HAVING AN
ISSUE HERE.
HOLD ON TO IT.
THERE ARE NOW SO MANY PARENTS
WHO ARE GOING THROUGH EXACTLY
WHAT YOU WENT THROUGH.
WHAT IS YOUR ADVICE TO THEM?
I MEAN, IT'S A JOURNEY THAT
DOESN'T END, THIS JOURNEY OF
GRIEF.
>> WELL, ALL I CAN SAY IS TO DIG
DEEP WITHIN YOURSELF.
AND IF YOU'RE A PERSON OF FAITH,
JUST TO PRAY REALLY HARD AND
SURROUND YOURSELF WITH LOVED
ONES OR FAMILY AND FRIENDS.
AND THINGS WILL GET BETTER IN
TIME.
BUT UNFORTUNATELY, IT'S A PAIN
THAT NEVER GOES AWAY.
I HAVE A HOLE IN MY HEART, AND I
WILL FOREVER.
BUT I'M JUST PRAYING FOR THEM,
THEY FIND SOME KIND OF PIECE.
PEACE.
>> AND I WANT TO BRING IN
AMARDEEP.
FOR YOU, YOUR LOSS WAS MORE
RECENT.
OBVIOUSLY, WHEN YOU HEARD OF
THIS, IT MUST HAVE ALL BROUGHT
IT BACK.
>> OH MY GOD, IT WAS SHOCKING.
WHEN WE HEARD IT, WE HAD A
TODDLER RUNNING AROUND THE
HOUSE.
AND WE JUST STARED AT HIM.
MY WIFE LOOKED AT ME.
SHE WORKS IN THE SCHOOLS.
I WAS A FORMER TEACHER.
SHE GOES HE WOULDN'T HAVE EVEN
RAN.
HE WOULD HAVE BEEN IN SHOCK.
WE STARTED CRYING.
WE COULDN'T STOP.
>> WHAT IS IT LIKE WHEN THERE IS
A LOT OF FOCUS IN THE IMMEDIATE
DAYS AFTER THIS, BUT THEN
ULTIMATELY REPORTERS GO AWAY,
AND A LOT OF THE WELL-WISHERS
AND THE COUNSELORS GO AWAY.
AND THE REST OF THE WORLD SORT
OF KEEPS SPINNING, BUT YOUR
WORLD HAS STOPPED?
I MEAN YOUR WORLD HAS COMPLETELY
CHANGED FOREVER.
HOW DO YOU COPE WITH THAT TIME
WHEN THE ADRENALINE FADES AWAY
AND THE REALITY SETS IN?
>> WELL, IN MY CASE, I WROTE A
BOOK, "AS GOOD AS SHE IMAGINED."
I STARTED A FOUNDATION IN MY
DAUGHTER'S NAME.
SO I'VE BEEN REALLY, REALLY BUSY
WITH THAT IT TAKES UP A LOT OF
MY TIME.
AND JUST GIVING BACK TO LESS
FORTUNATE CHILDREN IN OUR
COMMUNITY BY BUILDING
PLAYGROUNDS AND HELPING OUT THE
SCHOOLS WITH SMARTBOARDS AND
P.E. EQUIPMENT.
THAT HAS BEEN THERAPEUTIC AND
HEALING.
>> AMARDEEP, WHAT CAN COME OUT
OF THIS?
WE'VE SEEN FAR TOO MANY OF THESE
KINDS OF THINGS.
I KNOW YOU WANT SOMETHING TO
CHANGE.
SOMETHING'S GOT TO CHANGE.
>> I MEAN, THE NATIONAL DIALOGUE
HAS TO START.
ROXANNA AND I WITH MAYORS
AGAINST ILLEGAL GUNS.
AND WE JUST DID A WHOLE EVENT
WITH MAYOR BLOOMBERG THIS
MORNING OR THIS AFTERNOON.
AND, I MEAN, IT'S NOT JUST THE
GUNS THAT IS THE PROBLEM,
THOUGH.
AND IT'S BECOME LIKE A DEEP DOWN
ROOTED SOCIETAL ISSUE.
AND WE NEED TO KEEP THAT
CONVERSATION GOING.
AND FOR US, WE STARTED A
DOCUMENTARY CALLED NURSERY
CRIMES.
AND WE'RE GOING OUT OF OUR WAY
TO GO FIGURE OUT WHAT IS
HAPPENING AT A YOUNGER AND
YOUNGER AGE, AND HOW WE CAN FIND
THOSE PEOPLE THAT ARE ALMOST AT
THIS POINT OF SOCIOPATHY AND
THEN STOP IT AND BRING THEM
BACK.
>> THERE IS ALSO OBVIOUSLY
ISSUES OF MENTAL HEALTH THAT
NEED TO BE ADDRESSED.
IS THAT A CONCERN OF YOURS AS
WELL?
>> OH, ABSOLUTELY.
OUR SYSTEM HAS FAILED SO MANY
YOUNG PEOPLE.
AND, YOU KNOW, I THINK CONGRESS
AND THE PRESIDENT HAS TO WORK
REALLY, REALLY HARD TO COME UP
WITH A, YOU KNOW, GUN VIOLENCE
PROTECTION PLAN AND A BETTER
HEALTH CARE SYSTEM SO THESE KIND
OF SENSELESS TRAGEDIES DON'T
HAPPEN.
>> IT SEEMS LIKE SO MANY EVEN
PARENTS WHO KNOW THEIR CHILDREN
HAVE AN ISSUE, OR KNOW THEIR
YOUNG KIDS IN THEIR 20s HAVE AN
ISSUE, THEY CAN'T GET HELP
UNLESS THAT CHILD IS PROVEN TO
BE VIOLENT OR A THREAT TO
THEMSELVES OR TO OTHERS.
>> I MEAN, IT'S SAD.
MOST OF THE TIME THE CHILD
ACTUALLY HAS TO COMMIT A CRIME
BEFORE THEY'RE GOING TO BE ABLE
TO GET HELP.
AND A LOT OF TIMES MEDICAL
PEOPLE HAVE TO SAY THAT HEY, I
CAN'T HELP THEM UNTIL THEY DO
SOMETHING X, Y, Z BAD.
AND THAT'S A BROKEN SYSTEM.
BECAUSE WE CAN SEE YOUNGER AND
YOUNGER KIDS DOING SMALL THINGS
THAT WOULD BE SOCIOPATHIC OR
ISOLATED.
AND WE CAN GET THEM TO CONVERT
OR REVERT.
>> WHAT HAS BEEN IT BEEN LIKE
FOR YOU JUST TO WALK AROUND THIS
TOWN AND TO SEE -- TO SEE THE
OUTPOURING OF -- PEOPLE JUST
WANT TO BE HERE AND HUG ONE
ANOTHER.
>> I THINK IT'S VERY, VERY
SPECIAL.
IT'S SO HEARTBREAKING WHAT
HAPPENED HERE.
IT'S JUST DEVASTATING.
BUT TO SEE ALL THE PEOPLE COME
TOGETHER, WE JUST KNOW THAT
THERE HAS TO BE CHANGE AND HOPE
WITH THAT.
>> I APPRECIATE BOTH OF YOU
TALKING.
YOU WANTED TO BE HERE, TOO.
YOU WERE WALKING AROUND TO SEE
THE MEMORIALS.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
IT WAS AMAZING TO SEE ALL THE
SUPPORT IN THE COMMUNITY TO COME
OUT.
AND IT'S JUST ONE OF THOSE
THINGS THAT'S -- IT'S ONE THING
WHEN YOU LOOK AT A KID THAT
FALLS VICTIM TO THIS.
THEY CAN'T VOTE.
THEY CAN'T SIGN A PETITION.
THEY CAN'T GO OUT AND RALLY.
BUT IT'S US, THE ADULTS AT THIS
POINT IN TIME.
I MEAN, WE JUST SAW 20 INNOCENT
LIVES TAKEN WITH NO POINT TO IT.
IT WAS PERVERTED BEYOND BELIEF.
AND IT'S UP TO US TO PROTECT
THOSE CHILDREN AND THE CHILDREN
THAT ARE UP TO COME, YOU KNOW.
>> AMARDEEP, I APPRECIATE YOU
BEING HERE.
THANK YOU.
ROXANNA, THANK YOU.
>> THE LATEST ON THE
INVESTIGATION AS THE AUTHORITIES
LOOK AT THE KILLER'S COMPUTER.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI JOINS US WITH
THAT NEXT.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS SHELDON, WHOSE LONG DY
SETTING UP THE NEWS
STARTS WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND A CHOICE.
TAKE TYLENOL OR TAKE ALEVE,
THE #1 RECOMMENDED PAIN
RELIEVER BY ORTHOPEDIC DOCTORS.
JUST TWO ALEVE
CAN KEEP PAIN AWAY ALL DAY.
BACK TO THE NEWS.
JUST TWO ALEVE
CAN KEEP PAIN AWAY ALL DAY.
TO THE BEST VACATION
SP(ALL) THE GULF!
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHICH OF
OUR GREAT STATES FOLKS VISIT.
MISSISSIPPI,
ALABAMA,
LOUISIANA
OR FLORIDA,
THEY'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
SHAUL, YOUR ALABAMA
HOSPITALITY IS INCREDIBLE.
THANKS, KAREN.
LOVE YOUR MISSISSIPPI OUTDOORS.
I VOTE FOR YOUR
FLORIDA BEACHES, DAWN.
BILL, THIS LOUISIANA
SEAFOOD IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR ON THE GULF,
WE'VE DECIDED TO PUT
ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
NOW IS THE PERFECT TIME TO
VISIT ANYONE OF OUR STATES.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE, GO FISHING
OR JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
WE'VE GOT COASTLINE TO EXPLORE
AND WILDLIFE TO PHOTOGRAPH.
AND THERE'S WORLD CLASS DINING
WITH OUR WORLD FAMOUS SEAFOOD.
SO FOR A GREAT VACATION
THIS YEAR, COME TO THE GULF.
ITS ALL FABULOUS BUT
I GIVE FLORIDA THE EDGE.
RIGHT AFTER MISSISSIPPI.
YOU MEAN ALABAMA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
THIS INVITATION IS
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP
AND ALL OF US WHO
CALL THE GULF HOME.
ALRIWOAH! DID YOU GET THAT?
AND...FLIP!
YEP, LOOK AT THIS. IT TAKES
LIKE 20 PICTURES AT A TIME. I
NEVER MISS ANYTHING.
ISN'T THAT AWESOME?
UH THAT'S REALLY COOL.
YOU SHOULD UPLOAD THESE.
I KNOW, RIGHT?
THAT IS REALLY AMAZING.
THE PICTURES ARE SO CLEAR.
KEVIN'S A HANDSOME DEVIL
THAT PHONE DOES EVERYTHING!
SEARCH DOG TRICKS.
OKAY, SEE IF WE CAN TEACH
HIM SOMETHING COOL.
LOOK AT HOW LAZY KEVIN IS.
KEVIN, GET IT TOGETHER DUDE
CMON, KEVIN
TAKE 20 PICTURES WITH BURST
SHOT ON THE GALAXY S3.
>>> AS THE NEWTOWN COMMUNITY
CONTINUES TO STRUGGLE TO MAKE
SENSE OF THIS TRAGEDY, IF THAT'S
AT ALL POSSIBLE, POLICE ARE
TRYING TO PUT THE PIECES
TOGETHER AND FIGURE OUT JUST
WHAT HAPPENED.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI IS HERE WITH THE
LATEST.
WHAT ARE WE LEARNING ABOUT THE
INVESTIGATION AT THIS POINT?
>> WELL, THE NEWEST PART ABOUT
THE INVESTIGATION, ANDERSON, IS
THAT IT TURNS OUT THE SUSPECTED
SHOOTER IN THIS CASE DID GO TO
GUN RANGES A NUMBER OF TIMES
OVER THE LAST SEVERAL YEARS, AND
AS RECENTLY AS SIX MONTHS AGO.
NOW, HE MIGHT HAVE GONE MORE
RECENTLY THAN THAT, BUT THEY'RE
NOT THROUGH LOOKING AT ALL THE
GUN RANGES AND CONTACTING ALL OF
THEM TO FIND OUT ALL THE
INFORMATION.
>> DID HE GOOD ALONE?
>> WELL, THEY DID FIND EVIDENCE
THAT HE WENT AT LEAST ONCE WITH
HIS MOTHER.
THEY HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE TO PROVE
WHETHER THEY ACTUALLY WENT
TARGET SHOOTING TOGETHER AT THAT
GUN RANGE.
BUT THEY DID BOTH GO TOGETHER AT
LEAST ONCE.
>> AND HAVE THEY FOUND
INFORMATION AT HOME, ON
COMPUTERS OR ANYTHING LIKE THAT
THAT WE KNOW?
>> YEAH, THEY'VE BEEN EXAMINING
COMPUTERS THAT HAVE BEEN FOUND
AT THE HOME.
AND OUR SOURCES TELL US THAT
THEY WEREN'T IN GOOD ORDER --
THEY WERE SMASHED TO
SMITHEREENS.
AND NOW THEY LITERALLY HAD TO
PICK UP THE PIECES, TAKE THEM TO
THE CRIME LAB.
AND NOW THEY'RE GOING THROUGH
EVERYTHING, TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT WEBSITES HE VISITED, DID HE
TALK TO ANYBODY, WAS HE IN ANY
CHAT ROOMS, LEAVE ANY MESSAGES.
DID HE PLAY ANY VIDEO GAMES?
SO THEY'RE LOOKING AT ALL THESE
THINGS TO TRY TO FIGURE OUT.
AGAIN, IT'S ALL PART OF THE BIG
PICTURE HERE AND LOOKING FOR A
POSSIBLE MOTIVE.
>> AND AT THIS POINT, IS IT
KNOWN WHY THAT SCHOOL, WHY HE
PICKED THAT SCHOOL?
>> NO, IT ISN'T.
AND IN FACT, I TALKED WITH A
YOUNG MAN WHO WENT TO HIGH
SCHOOL WITH HIM, AND HE WENT
DOWN TO THE MEMORIAL TODAY
BECAUSE HE CAN'T BELIEVE WHAT
HAPPENED AND FEELS SO AWFUL FOR
THE CHILDREN.
BUT HE SAID THAT WHEN HE KNEW
HIM IN HIGH SCHOOL FOR ONE YEAR,
THEY WERE IN THE TECH CLUB
TOGETHER.
THEY LOVED PLAYING COMPUTERS.
HE LIKED PLAYING VIDEO GAMES.
AND HE MENTIONED TWO IN
PARTICULAR.
ONE CALLED "WARCRAFT III".
>> SURE.
>> ANOTHER ONE CALLED
"STARCRAFT."
AND IT INVOLVES SETTING UP AN
ENEMY CAMP AND YOU KILL THE
SOLDIERS AND ALL OF THIS.
HE SAID EVERYONE KNEW HE WAS
SOCIALLY AWKWARD, AND THAT HE
HAD SOME ISSUES GOING ON,
SOMETHING WITH HIS PERSONALITY.
BUT AS GUYS, THEY NEVER REALLY
TALKED ABOUT IT.
>> AND THEY'RE DOING A COMPLETE
LOOK AT THE WEAPONS THAT HE HAD
ACCESS TO?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
AS WE KNOW, HE CAME ARMED TO THE
HILT, OFFICIALS SAY.
NOT ONLY DID HE COME WITH THAT
HIGH CAPACITY MILITARY
ASSAULT-STYLE WEAPON AND THOSE
TWO HANDGUNS, BUT HE HAD
30-ROUND MAGAZINES FOR EACH OF
THEM, AND SEVERAL OF THEM FOR
EACH OF THEM, PLUS EXTRA AMMO ON
TOP OF THAT.
AND THEY'RE TRACING THE COMPLETE
HISTORY OF HOW OFTEN HE USED
THOSE GUNS, MAYBE WHERE HE USED
THE GUNS.
MAYBE HE USED SOME OF THOSE AT
THE GUN RANGE.
BUT WE DON'T KNOW.
>> IS THERE ANY MORE INFORMATION
ABOUT THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER?
>> THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER.
WELL, WE'RE FINDING OUT A LITTLE
BIT MORE ABOUT HER DIVORCE,
THROUGH DIVORCE PAPERS, FOR
EXAMPLE.
SHE WAS GETTING ALIMONY FROM HER
HUSBAND, ABOUT $290,000 A YEAR,
$24,000 A MONTH.
THE MARRIAGE BROKEN DOWN BECAUSE
OF IRRECONCILABLE DIFFERENCES.
AND THAT HE WAS TO BUY A CAR FOR
HIS SON AND HIS EX-WIFE WAS TO
BE RESPONSIBLE FOR THE MORTGAGE.
>> IS THAT PRETTY MUCH ALL AT
THIS POINT?
>> YEAH.
I MEAN, THEY'RE STILL LOOKING
FOR THE MOTIVE AND TRYING TO
TALK TO FAMILY, TO FRIENDS TO
TRY TO PAINT A PICTURE OF WHAT
HE WAS ALL ABOUT.
THERE IS SOME TALK FROM ONE
RELATIVE THAT NANCY LANZA --
WELL, EVERYONE DESCRIBES HER
MORE AS A GUN COLLECT EITHER
THIS POINT.
WE HAVEN'T HEARD ANYTHING OTHER
THAN THAT, ANY PROOF OF ANYTHING
ELSE RIGHT NOW.
BUT SHE WAS CONCERNED ABOUT THE
ECONOMY, BUT THERE IS NO
EVIDENCE THAT IT WENT BEYOND
THAT, YOU KNOW.
>> RIGHT.
>> WHY SHE WAS COLLECTING THESE
GUNS.
>> RIGHT.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI, I APPRECIATE
THAT THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR THE
LATEST ON THAT.
AFTER EVERY MASS SHOOTING, OF
COURSE, WE'RE ALL LEFT WITH THE
SAME QUESTION WHY, WHY DID THIS
HAPPEN.
WHAT LEADS SOMEONE DOWN TO GUN
DOWN COMPLETE STRANGERS?
DO THESE KILLERS HAVE ANYTHING
IN COMMON?
WHAT DOES HISTORY ACTUALLY SHOW
US?
BECAUSE WHAT IS FASCINATING IS
OFTEN WHAT WE THINK WE KNOW
ABOUT THESE SHOOTINGS, ABOUT THE
PEOPLE WHO DO THEM, IT'S
ACTUALLY VERY DIFFERENT THAN
WHAT THE REALITY IS.
AND OFTEN IT TAKES YEARS TO
LEARN THE TRUTH ABOUT THESE
PEOPLE.
CHIEF MEDICAL CORRESPONDENT DR.
SANJAY GUPTA JOINS ME JUST
AHEAD.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH A SELECT TERRAIN DIAL
THAT ADJUSTS THE JEEP
GRAND CHEROKEE'S PERFORMANCE
FOR SPECIFIC WEATHER
AND ROAD CONDITIONS...
♪
...EVEN HEAVY SNOWSTORMS...
WON'T KEEP YOU
FROM GETTING TO WORK.
OUR APOLOGIES.
♪
>>> IT WAS DEVASTATING TO KNOW
THAT SOMEONE HAD COME INTO THE
SCHOOL WITH A GUN.
THAT ALONE WAS HORRIBLE ENOUGH,
BECAUSE IT'S A PLACE OF PEACE
AND JOY.
BUT NOW AS WE GO FORWARD AND
WE'VE LEARNED THE NAMES, AND NOW
WE'RE GOING THROUGH THE GRUELING
PROCESS OF THE FUNERALS, IT'S
VERY, VERY, VERY HARD.
EVERYONE USES THE WORD HOLLOW.
THAT'S WHERE WE'RE AT RIGHT NOW.
>> WE'RE GOING TO CONTINUE TO
FOCUS ON THE VICTIMS OF FRIDAY'S
SHOOTING.
WE'RE GOING BRING YOU JUST A
LITTLE BIT OF MY INTERVIEW WITH
THE McDONNELL FAMILY, WHOSE
DAUGHTER GRACE WAS KILLED ON
FRIDAY.
WE'RE GOING TO PLAY THE WHOLE
INTERVIEW FOR YOU TOMORROW
NIGHT.
BUT WE'LL PLAY JUST A LITTLE BIT
A LITTLE BIT LATER ON TO HONOR
GRACE, AMAZING GRACE, AS WE
TALKED ABOUT IN THE INTERVIEW.
BUT THERE ARE MANY UNANSWERED
QUESTIONS THAT INVOLVES THIS
KILLER.
WHY TARGET AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL?
WHY THIS SCHOOL?
WHY DID HE MURDER 20 FIRST
GRADERS, LITTLE KIDS JUST 6 AND
7 YEARS OLD, YOUNG ENOUGH TO
BELIEVE IN SANTA CLAUS AND THE
TOOTH FAIRY.
AS WE SAID EARLIER TODAY,
AUTHORITIES ARE EXAMINING A
COMPUTER SMASHED IN THE GUNMAN'S
HOME.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI SPOKE ABOUT
THAT.
THAT MAY OR MAY NOT CONTAIN SOME
CLUES.
INVESTIGATORS MAY NEVER FIGURE
OUT WHAT HAPPENED.
SADLY, THOUGH, THERE IS A BODY
OF RESEARCH ON THESE KIND OF
KILLERS, ON MASS MURDERERS, AND
THE COMMON GROUND THEY MAY
SHARE.
DR. SANJAY GUPTA JOINS ME.
HE HAS BEEN LOOKING INTO THAT.
YOU'VE BEEN RESEARCHING
COMMONALITIES.
WHAT ARE THEY?
WHAT HAVE YOU FOUND?
>> ONE OF THE FIRST THINGS THAT
THESE MEDICAL INVESTIGATORS,
FORENSIC INVESTIGATORS WILL DO
IS TRY AND FIGURE OUTDO THEY FIT
A PARTICULAR TYPE.
AND THEY ALMOST ALWAYS DO, WHICH
IS INTERESTING.
THERE ARE TYPICALLY THREE TYPES
THAT WE'RE TALKING ABOUT HERE.
SOMEONE WHO ACTUALLY HAS
PSYCHOTIC TENDENCIES, SOMEONE
WHO HAS PSYCHOPATHIC TENDENCIES,
OR SOMEONE WHO HAS BEEN HEAVILY
TRAUMATIZED IN YOUTH.
JARED LOUGHNER, FOR EXAMPLE,
SOMEBODY WE REPORTED ON QUITE A
BIT.
HE CLEARLY HAD PSYCHOTIC
TENDENCIES.
AND ONE OF THE COLUMBINE KILLERS
HAD CLEAR CLUES DATING BACK OF
PSYCHOPATHIC TENDENCIES.
HE HAD SADISTIC BEHAVIOR.
HE HAD BEEN DELINQUENT WITH HIS
PARENTS QUITE A BIT.
AND I DON'T KNOW IF YOU REMEMBER
THIS, ANDERSON, BUT HE WAS
LAUGHING AT THE TIME THAT HE WAS
ACTUALLY COMMITTING THESE
MURDERS AT COLUMBINE HIGH
SCHOOL.
THE POINT IS THAT HARDLY ANYONE
EVER REALLY JUST SNAPS.
WE HAVE THE BENEFIT OF HINDSIGHT
IN THESE SITUATIONS.
BUT THE REAL POINT HERE IS THAT
WERE THERE SOME CLUES?
AND THERE ALMOST ALWAYS IS.
>> THAT NOTION OF JUST SNAPPING,
THAT DOESN'T REALLY TURN OUT TO
BE THE CASE, THAT USUALLY THERE
ARE PEOPLE WHO ACTUALLY --
SOMETIMES I'VE HEARD -- THERE
WAS A SECRET SERVICE REPORT DONE
THAT THEY ACTUALLY TALKED TO
OTHER KIDS, OTHER PEOPLE WHAT
THEY'RE GOING TO DO.
>> AND IF THEY DO THAT, A VERY
IMPORTANT POINT, IF THEY
ACTUALLY TALK TO SOMEONE AS
OPPOSED TO BEING ISOLATED, IT IS
A GREAT INHIBITOR OF CARRYING
OUT THE ACTIVITY.
ONCE YOU START TO TALK TO OTHER
PEOPLE, EITHER BECAUSE THEY TALK
YOU OUT OF IT, OR YOU YOURSELF
GET SOME GREATER CONTEXT OF WHAT
IT IS YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT IT
ALMOST ALWAYS INHIBITS THE
ACTIVITY.
SIMPLY TALKING ABOUT IT WITH A
LOVED ONE AND OTHER PEOPLE IN
THE SCHOOL.
COLUMBINE WAS UNUSUAL THAT WAY
BECAUSE THERE WAS TWO PEOPLE
TOGETHER.
BUT ALMOST ALWAYS IT IS A SINGLE
PERSON WHO HAS NOT DISCUSSED
THIS PLAN WITH ANYBODY ELSE.
>> YOU TALK ABOUT SOME OF THE
MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES.
ARE A LOT OF THEM ON MEDICATION,
OFF MEDICATION?
>> THIS IS REALLY INTERESTING.
ALMOST ALL OF THEM WERE ON SOME
TYPE OF MEDICATION.
AND IF YOU DIG A LITTLE BIT DEEP
WITH THAT, WHAT YOU FIND IS THAT
THERE IS A VULNERABLE PERIOD.
IT IS WHEN SOMEONE IS STARTING
MEDICATIONS OR WHEN THEY'RE
GOING OFF.
AND TYPICALLY THEY'RE
ANTIDEPRESSANTS.
NOT ALL PSYCHOTROPIC
MEDICATIONS.
AT THAT POINT WHEN THEY'RE
EITHER GOING ON OR GOING OFF,
THEY CAN BE A GREAT BENEFIT, BUT
YOU CAN HAVE INCREASED
IMPULSIVENESS, DECREASED
JUDGMENT AND LOSS OF TOUCH WITH
REALITY.
THOSE ARE THE THREE SYMPTOMS
THAT THEY DESCRIBED TO ME.
AND REMEMBER, ANDERSON, THEY
SHOULD BE MONITORED AT THAT
TIME.
BUT IN A MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEM
THE WAY IT IS NOW, THEY GET THE
PRESCRIPTION, AND HARDLY ANY
FOLLOW-UP.
>> DOCTORS HAVE TOLD ME THAT IF
YOU ARE ON ANTIDEPRESSANTS AND
YOU JUST STOP, THAT YOU SHOULD
NOT JUST STOP.
YOU REALLY NEED TO BE UNDER
SUPERVISION AND TAPER OFF.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> AND IT SEEMS LIKE SOME OF
THESE PEOPLE DIDN'T.
>> NO.
AND YOU KNOW, THE WHOLE
MONITORING NOTION INVOLVES
BUILDING TRUST WITH A
PSYCHIATRIST, BEING ABLE TO CALL
THAT PERSON, NOT SIMPLY GETTING
A PRESCRIPTION.
AND, YOU KNOW, THIS ISN'T TO
INDICT THE MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEM.
BUT IT'S BASICALLY SAYING THERE
IS NOT ENOUGH RESOURCES.
THEY CAN BARELY SEE THE PEOPLE
THAT THEY NEED TO SEE.
THIS IDEA OF BEING ABLE TO
MONITOR THEM, AGAIN, AT THESE
VULNERABLE PERIODS, IT'S NOT
HAPPENING.
I TALKED TO SEVERAL OF THEM.
THIS IS INCREDIBLY FRUSTRATING
FOR THEM.
>> ALSO OVER THE YEARS THERE HAS
BEEN A LOT OF FOCUS ON THE
RIGHTS OF THE PATIENT,
UNDERSTANDABLY, BECAUSE THERE
WERE ABUSES BEFORE.
I GUESS I WONDER, HAS IT GONE
TOO FAR?
I'VE HEARD FROM PARENTS WHO SAY
THEY KNOW THEY HAVE TROUBLES
WITH A CHILD OR WITH EVEN AN
ADULT CHILD, BUT THEY CAN'T DO
SOMETHING UNLESS THAT PERSON HAS
COMMITTED A CRIME OR IS PROVEN
TO BE DANGEROUS.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
IMMINENT THREAT TO THEMSELVES OR
TO OTHERS.
WHAT AN UNBELIEVABLE STANDARD.
THINK ABOUT IT.
IT'S LIKE SAYING YOU WOULD HAVE
TO BE HAVING A HEART ATTACK TO
BE TREATED FOR YOUR HEART
DISEASE.
IT JUST DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
IT GOES AGAINST EVERYTHING WE
THINK OF AS DOCTORS.
THE OTHER OPTION IS BASICALLY TO
PUT THEM INTO THE CRIMINAL
JUSTICE SYSTEM.
AND NOW YOU'RE ASKING PARENTS TO
ESSENTIALLY CREATE A POLICE
RECORD FOR YOUR CHILD.
>> AND FRANKLY, THAT IS THE
REALITY THAT IS HAPPENING.
I MEAN, OUR PRISONS ARE FULL OF
PEOPLE WHO HAVE MENTAL ISSUES.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
PEOPLE ALWAYS TALK ABOUT THIS
NOTION THAT FAMILIES ARE DENYING
THE SYMPTOMS, IGNORING THEM.
THAT COULD BE HAPPENING, BUT THE
PEOPLE I TALK TO, THAT'S NOT THE
CASE.
THESE FAMILIES, THEY ANGUISH
OVER WHAT IS HAPPENING WITH
THEIR CHILDREN.
THEY DON'T HAVE GOOD OPTIONS.
EVEN IF THEY GET THE MEDS, THEY
ARE TO BE MONITORED, ESPECIALLY
WHEN GOING ON AND OFF.
AND THEY DON'T GET THAT.
THERE ARE SO MANY POTENTIAL
BREAKDOWNS IN THE SYSTEM.
THESE ARE FIXABLE PROBLEMS.
BUT IT'S NOT WORKING THE WAY IT.
>> AND THERE JUST NEEDS TO BE A
WILL AND A CONTINUED DISCUSSION.
OFTEN WE DISCUSS THESE THINGS IN
THE MEDIA IN THE WAKE OF
SOMETHING LIKE THIS AND STOP,
AND NOTHING EVER CHANGES.
SANJAY, I APPRECIATE THE REPORT.
A LOT OF PEOPLE THINK THAT
MASS SHOOTERS ARE LONER THAT IS
SNAP AND GO ON KILLING SPREES.
IN HER BOOK "RAMPAGE: THE SOCIAL
ROOTS OF SCHOOL SHOOTINGS,"
KATHERINE NEWMAN SAYS IT'S NOT
THAT SIMPLE, NOT BY A LONG SHOT.
SHE HAS DONE A LOT OF RESEARCH
ON SCHOOL SHOOTINGS.
I APPRECIATE YOU BEING BACK ON
THE PROGRAM.
YOU'VE STUDIED RAMPAGE SHOOTINGS
LIKE THE ONE DATING BACK TO THE
1970s.
YOU SAY THERE ARE A LOT OF MYTHS
ABOUT THEM.
TALK TO ME ABOUT SOME OF THE
MYTHS.
>> ONE OF THE MYTHS IS THE IDEA
THAT PEOPLE SNAP.
BUT WE FOUND THAT SOMETIMES THEY
PLAN THESE THINGS AS MUCH AS
NINE MONTHS IN ADVANCE.
ANOTHER MYTH IS THAT THEY ARE
LONERS.
THEY'RE VERY RARELY LONERS, BUT
THEY'RE PEOPLE WHO HAVE A LOT OF
TROUBLE IN THEIR SOCIAL
INTERACTIONS THERE IS FRICTION
ALL AROUND THEM.
I HAVE TO SAY CONTRARY TO WHAT
YOU WERE JUST TALKING ABOUT, IN
THE CASE OF THE SHOOTERS WE
LOOKED AT, THEY WERE ALMOST
NEVER DIAGNOSED OR UNDER
TREATMENT.
AND SO THEY'RE OFTEN PEOPLE WHO
ARE COMPLETELY MISSED BY THE
MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEM.
AND WE FIND OUT ABOUT THEIR
MENTAL DISORDERS IN FORENSIC
SEGMENTS AFTER THE FACT.
WE ALSO DISCOVER THAT THEY TELL
PEOPLE A LOT ABOUT WHAT THEY'RE
PLANNING TO DO, BUT THEY DO SO
IN A WAY THAT IS VERY DIFFICULT
TO INTERPRET.
THEY SAY THINGS THAT ARE RATHER
VEILED AND CONFUSING.
AND BECAUSE WHAT THEY PLAN TO DO
IS SO OUTLANDISH AND SO
INCONCEIVABLE, THE PEOPLE AROUND
THEM DON'T REALLY KNOW HOW TO
INTERPRET WHAT THEY'VE HEARD.
SO THEY GET A LOT OF INFORMATION
CIRCULATING, BUT THAT DOESN'T
COME TO THE ADULTS WHO MIGHT BE
ABLE TO INTERVENE BECAUSE THE
KIDS HAVE A HARD TIME
INTERPRETING EXACTLY WHAT THOSE
VEILED WARNINGS MEAN.
>> I MEAN, WE SEEM TO SEE MOSTLY
MALES, YOUNG MALES COMMITTING
THESE HORRIBLE CRIMES.
IS THERE -- IS THERE A REASON
WHY THAT IS?
>> WELL, GIRLS DO OTHER THINGS,
I'M SORRY TO SAY THAT ARE
DAMAGING TO THEMSELVES.
BUT THEY TEND TO BE TURNING
INWARD, WHERE AS BOYS TEND TO BE
EXPLODING OUTWARD.
AND THAT'S PARTLY BECAUSE OF THE
IMAGES THAT THEY RECEIVE IN
POPULAR CULTURE, WHICH LIONIZE
THIS KIND OF VIOLENCE.
OBVIOUSLY NOT AGAINST CHILDREN,
BUT THE TRENCH COAT MAFIA, THE
SORT OF GUNMAN IS A FIGURE WE
RECOGNIZE.
AND FROM THE VIEWPOINT OF THESE
VERY MARGINAL BOYS, IT LOOKS
MORE APPEALING THAN THE DWEEBIE
LONER MISFIT.
AND SO WHAT THEY'RE SEEKING TO
DO MOST OF THE TIME IS SOLVE A
PROBLEM.
AND THE PROBLEM IS THEY DON'T
LIKE THE WAY OTHER PEOPLE
PERCEIVE THEM, AND THEY WANT TO
CHANGE IT.
AND WHEN THEY START TALKING
ABOUT SHOOTING PEOPLE, ALL OF
THE SUDDEN THOSE PEER GROUPS
START PAYING ATTENTION TO THEM.
AND NOW THEY'VE MADE A
COMMITMENT OR PROMISE WHAT
THEY'RE GOING TO DO, AND THEY
FIND THEY CAN'T BACK DOWN OUT OF
IT OR IT WOULD BE ONE MORE
SOCIAL FAILURE.
>> THAT'S INTERESTING.
SO IN SOME CASES, ACTUALLY
TALKING ABOUT IT, HAVING SAID
SOMETHING TO OTHERS, IT KIND OF
BUILDS UP THE MOMENTUM OR THE
PRESSURE FOR THEM TO ACTUALLY
ACT OUT ON IT?
>> IT DOES, ANDERSON.
I MEAN, THEY'RE USUALLY QUITE
AMBIVALENT ABOUT WHAT THEY'RE
GOING TO DO.
BUT WHAT PUSHES THEM PAST THE
AMBIVALENCE IS THE POSSIBILITY
THAT THEY MIGHT HAVE ONE MORE
COMPLETE SOCIAL DISASTER IN
WHICH THEY'VE MADE PROMISES, AND
NOW THEY'RE NOT GOING TO FULFILL
THEM, AND EVERYBODY IS GOING TO
BE LAUGHING AT THEM NOW.
AND IT IS AMAZING HOW MUCH THAT
MOTIVATE THIS IS BEHAVIOR.
THEY'RE NOT THINKING ABOUT HOW
THEY'RE GOING TO KILL PEOPLE OR
DESTROY A TOWN.
THEY'RE THINKING ABOUT HOW OTHER
PEOPLE ARE GOING TO SEE THEM
DIFFERENTLY.
LOOK AT THE PICTURES OF THE
SHOOTER IN THE VIRGINIA TECH
CASE.
THERE HE WAS WITH GUNS BLAZING
AND A FLAK JACKET, AND HE LOOKS
LIKE RAMBO.
WELL, THAT LOOKS A LOT BETTER TO
HIM, I'M SORRY TO SAY THAN THE
DWEEBIE IMAGE OF THE REJECT AND
MISFIT.
>> AND JUST VERY BRIEFLY,
POLITICIANS TALK VIDEO GAMES.
DOES THAT -- HAVE YOU SEEN ANY
LINK?
>> THERE IS A LINK, ANDERSON,
BUT IT'S NOT THE LINK WE USUALLY
THINK OF.
OFTEN PEOPLE THINK THAT VIDEO
GAMES WILL SOMEHOW INSPIRE
PEOPLE TO FEEL RAGE AND GO OUT
AND ENACT IT.
INSTEAD, WHAT WE SAW WAS THAT
VIDEO GAMES JUST LIKE FILMS
PRESENT AN IMAGE OF MASCULINITY
THAT IS TIED TO VIOLENCE, AND
SORT OF GLAMORIZES IT, AND MAKES
THESE BOYS WHO DON'T FEEL VERY
GLAMOROUS THAT IF THEY CAN JUST
DO THAT, OTHER PEOPLE ARE GOING
TO TURN AROUND AND LOOK AT THEM
DIFFERENTLY.
RATHER THAN INSPIRING A KIND OF
BOILING RAGE, WHAT IT DOES IS
PRESENT AN IMAGE OF HOW A
MASCULINE BOY, YOU KNOW, COULD
ACT AND BE NOTICED.
>> RIGHT.
INTERESTING.
KATHERINE NEWMAN, I APPRECIATE
YOU BEING ON.
WE'LL TALK TO YOU AGAIN.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
SOME OF THE ADULTS IN NEWTOWN
ARE GETTING COMFORT FROM
VOLUNTEERS ON FOUR LEGS.
HOW THESE AMAZING THERAPY DOGS
FOUND THEIR WAY HERE, IN JUST A
MOMENT.
[ baby crying ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
ROBITUSSIN® LIQUID FORMULA
SOOTHES YOUR THROAT ON CONTACT
AND THE ACTIVE INGREDIENT
RELIEVES YOUR COUGH.
ROBITUSSIN®. DON'T SUFFER
THE COUGHEQUENCES™.
WE BELIEVE THE MORE YOU KNOW,
THE BETTER YOU TRADE.
SO WE HAVE ONGOING WEBINARS
AND INTERACTIVE LEARNING,
PLUS, IN-BRANCH SEMINARS
AT OVER 500 LOCATIONS,
WHERE OUR DEDICATED SUPPORT
TEAMS HELP YOU KNOW MORE
SO YOUR MONEY CAN DO MORE.
[ Rodger ] AT SCOTTRADE,
SEVEN DOLLAR TRADES
ARE JUST THE START.
OUR TEAMS HAVE THE
INFORMATION YOU WANT
WHEN YOU NEED IT.
IT'S ANOTHER REASON
MORE INVESTORS ARE SAYING...
[ All ]
I'M WITH SCOTTRADE.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME FOR CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
>>> THE LITTLE GIRLS WITH
PRESIDENT OBAMA ARE EMILIE
PARKER'S SISTERS.
6-YEAR-OLD EMILIE WAS ONE OF THE
20 CHILDREN KILLED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
PRESIDENT OBAMA MET WITH
VICTIMS' FAMILIES AND FIRST
RESPONDERS LAST NIGHT BEFORE HE
SPOKE AT THAT MEMORIAL SERVICE.
>> YOU MUST KNOW THAT WHATEVER
MEASURE OF COMFORT WE CAN
PROVIDE, WE WILL PROVIDE IT.
WHATEVER PORTION OF SADNESS THAT
WE CAN SHARE WITH YOU TO EASE
THIS HEAVY LOAD, WE WILL GLADLY
BEAR IT.
NEWTOWN, YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
>> THEY ARE NOT.
SO MANY STRANGERS HAVE REACHED
OUT TO THIS BROKEN COMMUNITY,
INCLUDING SOME VOLUNTEERS WHO
DROVE HERE FROM THE MIDWEST WITH
THEIR THERAPY DOGS.
I'VE SAID BEFORE THAT WORDS CAN
SEEM SO SMALL AT TIMES LIKE
THIS.
AND THERE ARE NO WORDS, REALLY.
AND THAT'S WHAT IS SO GREAT
ABOUT DOGS.
HERE IS GARY TUCHMAN.
>> Reporter: NINE GOLDEN
RETRIEVERS ON THE MARCH, MAKING
THEIR WAY INTO A RECREATION
CENTER IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
FOR AN EMOTIONAL RESCUE TO HELP
COMFORT THE CHILDREN WHO
SURVIVED THE ATTACK AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY AND OTHER
CHILDREN IN TOWN.
THERAPEUTIC CANINES ARE
SPONSORED AND TRAINED BY
LUTHERAN CHURCH CHARITIES,
TRANSPORTED IN A VAN FOR A
900-MILE RIDE FROM ILLINOIS.
>> LET ME GIVE YOU A QUICK
INTRODUCTION TO THE DOGS HERE.
THIS IS CHEWY.
THIS IS RUTHIE, ABBY, PRINCE,
LUTHER.
>> MAGGIE.
HANNA.
>> BARNEY.
>> BARNEY, AND?
>> SHAMMY.
>> THESE ARE THE COMFORT DOGS.
>> Reporter: WHAT IS A COMFORT
DOG?
>> A COMFORT DOG IS ONE WHO
BRINGS COMFORT TO OTHER PEOPLE
WHEN THEY'RE SUFFERING OR
HURTING, OR BRING HAPPINESS TO
PEOPLE.
IT HELPS PEOPLE PROCESS THEIR
GRIEF.
>> Reporter: SO IT'S SPECIALLY
TRAINED?
>> THEY ARE SPECIALLY TRAINED.
THESE ARE ALL SPECIALLY TRAINED
SERVICE DOGS.
WE DON'T USE THEM WITH DISABLED,
WE TRAIN THEM ADDITIONALLY TO
WORK WITH ALL DIFFERENT AGE
GROUPS AND PEOPLE.
TO SOME PEOPLE, AND WE'VE SEEN
THIS WITH CHILDREN, IT BRINGS A
SENSE OF CALMNESS IN A TIME OF
CONFUSION OR THE THEM DURING
THIS PERIOD.
TO SOME IT HELPS THEM PROCESS
THEIR GRIEF.
THEY'LL START CRYING, AND
THEY'LL HUG THE DOG.
AND TO SOME CHILDREN THEY'LL
COME UP SAD AND THEY'LL WALK
AWAY HAPPY.
>> Reporter: DO YOU KNOW THAT
LUTHER IS INCAPABLE OF BEING
MEAN?
LUTHER IS A FRIENDLY DOG.
>> HAYDEN LOVES DOGS.
>> Reporter: WHEN DOES TRAINING
BEGIN TO BE A COMFORT DOG?
>> 5 1/2 WEEKS.
WE BUY PUPPIES AT 5 1/2 WEEKS
AND TURN THEM UPSIDE DOWN AND
HOW THEIR TEMPERAMENT IS.
FROM THAT POINT ON --
>> Reporter: YOU TURN THEM
UPSIDE DOWN.
IF THEY ARE TURNED UPSIDE DOWN
AND THEY FLAIL, THEY CAN'T BE A
COMFORT DOG?
>> RIGHT.
OUR INITIAL SCREENING IS IF THEY
CAN BE RELAXED IN THAT POSITION,
THEN WE START THE NEXT PROCESS,
WHICH IS A TRAIN THAER WORKS ON
ONE-ON-ONE FOR THE NEXT EIGHT
MONTHS TO A YEAR.
>> Reporter: AND WHERE ELSE HAVE
YOUR DOGS BEEN?
WHAT OTHER DISASTERS?
>> OUR DOGS A MONTH AGO WHEN
SANDY HIT, WE WERE OUT IN NEW
YORK AND NEW JERSEY.
WE HAVE BEEN IN INDIANA WITH THE
FLOODINGS.
WE HAD DOGS OUT IN JOPLIN,
MISSOURI.
>> Reporter: COME HERE!
THIS IS LUTHER.
HE IS A COMFORT DOG.
YOU CAN PET HIM.
IT SAYS RIGHT HERE, "PLEASE PET
ME."
HOW DO YOU FEEL WHEN YOU SEE A
CHILD COME UP TO ONE OF YOUR
DOGS WHO HAS BEEN IN THIS
SITUATION AND HAS A BIG SMILE ON
THEIR FACE?
>> TEARS.
THEY SMILE, I CRY.
>> Reporter: AND AMID THE
CONTINUING SADNESS HERE, THERE
WERE A LOT OF SMILES.
>> NOTHING BETTER THAN SEEING
DOG'S TAIL WAGGING LIKE THAT.
GARY TUCHMAN JOINS ME NOW.
THE DOGS WERE GREAT.
WERE YOU ABLE TO TELL THE HOW
THE PARENTS OF SANDY HOOK
REACTED TO THEM?
>> IT'S A LITTLE HARD TO HEAR
WHAT YOU SAID.
I THINK YOU'RE ASKING ABOUT HOW
THIS ALL WORKS.
LET ME TELL YOU MY UNSCIENTIFIC
FINES OF WHAT I LEARNED TODAY.
KIDS LOVE STUFFED ANIMALS,
ESPECIALLY BIG STUFFED ANIMALS.
THESE ARE BASICALLY BIG STUFFED
ANIMALS THAT WALK, WAG THEIR
TAILS AND LICK.
THEY DON'T BITE, THEY DON'T
GROWL, AND THEY WANT TO BE
PETTED 100% OF THE TIME.
IT'S VERY COMFORTING FOR THE
CHILDREN.
WHAT WE'RE BASICALLY FINDING IS
THIS IS THE EXACT ANTITHESIS OF
WHAT HAPPENED IN THIS TOWN ON
FRIDAY.
>> YEAH, GARY, I APPRECIATE THAT
REPORT.
BRINGING A SMILE TO A LOT OF
PEOPLE'S FACES TODAY.
GARY, THANKS.
>>> COMING UP NEXT, THE PARENTS
OF GRACE McDONNELL REMEMBER
THEIR DAUGHTER, THE AMAZING GIRL
THEY CALLED GRACIE.
[ Female Announcer ]
WHAT IF THE NEXT BIG THING,
ISN'T A THING AT ALL?
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
CONNECTING
TO THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
♪ BUT THE FIRE IS
SO DELIGHTFUL ♪
NOTHING MELTS AWAY THE COLD
LIKE A HOT, DELICIOUS BOWL
OF CHICKEN NOODLE SOUP
FROM CAMPBELL'S.
♪ LET IT SNOW, LET IT SNOW
>>> LOOKING AT PICTURES OF A
LIVE VIGIL AT THE MAKESHIFT
MEMORIAL THAT IS GROWING WITH
EACH PASSING DAY AND NIGHT.
EARLIER I MENTIONED I SPOKE WITH
THE PARENTS OF GRACE McDONNELL.
TODAY THEY INVITED US INTO THEIR
HOME.
THEY WANTED TO SPEAK ABOUT THEIR
DAUGHTER.
CHRIS AND LYNN McDONNELL HELPED
US TO GET TO KNOW GRACE AND THE
HAPPINESS SHE BROUGHT THEM AND
THEIR SON JACK AND EVERYONE SHE
TOUCHED.
WE'RE GOING TO BRING YOU THAT
FULL INTERVIEW TOMORROW.
WE'RE GOING TO SHARE SOME OF
WHAT THEY SAID WITH YOU TONIGHT.
LYNN McDONNELL TOLD US HOW THEY
DON'T WANT TO HAVE HATE IN THEIR
HEARTS WHAT HAPPENED.
LISTEN TO SOME OF WHAT SHE HAD
TO SAY.
>> I HAD SAID THAT TO JACK, THAT
IT'S OKAY TO BE ANGRY BECAUSE
SURE, WE HAVE ANGER AND WE'RE
UPSET AND WE DON'T KNOW WHY.
BUT I TOLD JACK THAT HE COULD
NEVER LIVE WITH HATE.
GRACE DIDN'T HAVE AN OUNCE OF
HATE IN HER.
AND SO WE HAVE TO LIVE THROUGH
GRACE AND REALIZE THAT HATE IS
NOT HOW OUR FAMILY IS AND
CERTAINLY NOT HOW GRACE IS.
AND I KNOW ALL THOSE BEAUTIFUL
LITTLE CHILDREN.
THEY DIDN'T HAVE ANY HATE IN
THEM EITHER.
SO WE'LL JUST TAKE THE LEAD FROM
THEM AND WE WILL NOT GO DOWN
THAT ROAD.
BUT WE'LL LET THEM GUIDE US.
>> DURING THE INTERVIEW, WE WERE
TALKING ABOUT GRACE.
AND I MENTIONED THAT ONE OF MY
FAVORITE SONGS IS "AMAZING
GRACE," AND THAT IT ALWAYS MAKES
ME CRY.
I SAID I'LL NEVER HEAR THAT SONG
AGAIN WITHOUT THINKING OF THEIR
GRACE.
AND LYNN LIKED THAT IDEA.
BUT SHE WANTED TO MAKE SURE THAT
WHEN YOU HEAR THAT SONG, YOU
SMILE, THAT YOU DON'T CRY.
ANOTHER THING THAT LYNN SAID
THAT GIVES HER SOME COMFORT TO
THINK THAT GRACE DIED WITH HER
FRIENDS, AND THAT THEY WERE
HOLDING HANDS WHEN THEY DIED.
SHE LIKES TO THINK OF THEM ALL
IN HEAVEN, ALL 20 OF THOSE
LITTLE CHILDREN, ALL HOLDING
HANDS TOGETHER RIGHT NOW.
♪ AMAZING GRACE HOW SWEET THE
SOUND ♪
♪ THAT SAVED A WRETCH LIKE ME
♪ I ONCE WAS LOST BUT NOW I'M
FOUND ♪
♪ WAS BLIND BUT NOW I SEE
♪ THROUGH MANY DANGERS, TOILS,
AND SNARES, WE HAVE ALREADY
COME ♪
♪ TWAS GRACE THAT BROUGHT US
SAFE THUS FAR ♪
♪ AND GRACE WILL LEAD US HOME
♪ AMAZING GRACE HOW SWEET THE
SOUND, THAT SAVED A WRETCH LIKE
ME ♪