>> I KNOWN HER SENSE 1992, WHEN
HER HUSBAND WAS ELECTED
PRESIDENT.
YOU KNOW HER.
SHE'S NOT THE TYPE THAT WILL
REST AND TAKE IT EASY.
>> DOCTORS ARE PRESCRIBING BRAIN
REST.
I'M SURE IT'S THE LAST THING SHE
WANTS TO HEAR, WOLF.
>> WELL, WE OF COURSE, YOU AND
ALL OF OUR VIEWERS WISH THE
SECRETARY OF STATE A COMPLETE
AND SPEEDY RECOVERY.
SPECIAL COVERAGE OF THE DISASTER
HERE IN CONNECTICUT CONTINUES
RIGHT NOW.
>> SHE WAS THE TYPE OF PERSON
THAT COULD LIGHT UP A ROOM.
SHE -- SHE ALWAYS HAD SOMETHING
KIND TO SAY ABOUT ANYBODY.
>> GRIEVING FATHER ON HIS
BEAUTIFUL 6-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER,
GUNNED DOWN, GUNNED DOWN IN HER
OWN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THIS HOUR, UNSPEAKABLE PAIN AND
UNANSWERED QUESTIONS IN THE
MASSACRE THAT HAS SHATTERED A
QUIET TOWN AND STUNNED THE
NATION.
WE WANT TO WELCOME OUR VIEWERS
IN THE UNITED STATES AND AROUND
THE WORLD.
I'M WOLF BLITZER REPORTING LIVE
RIGHT NOW FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THE 20 CHILDREN GUNNED DOWN IN
THEIR OWN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WERE
6 AND 7 YEARS OLD.
THEY WERE PRACTICALLY BABIES, AS
THE PEOPLE HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, MOURN.
WE NOW KNOW THE NAMES OF THE
VICTIMS OF THE SCHOOL MASSACRE.
AUTHORITIES RELEASING THE LIST
JUST A LITTLE WHILE AGO.
WE'RE ALSO LEARNING JUST HOW
BRUTALLY THEY DIED.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER SAYS, EVERY
ONE OF THE 26 VICTIMS WERE SHOT
MORE THAN ONCE, APPARENTLY WITH
A SEMIAUTOMATIC.
THE RELATIVES OF THE SHOOTER ARE
STRUGGLING TO COMPETENT WHEN THE
LOSS OF LIFE, INCLUDING NANCY,
WHO WAS GUNNED DOWN BY HER SON.
NO WORD ON A MOTIVE.
POLICE SAY THEY HAVE FOUND VERY
GOOD EVIDENCE AT THE SCHOOL AND
AT THE LANZA HOME.
FOR MORE RIGHT NOW ON THE
INVESTIGATION, LET'S BRING IN
OUR NATIONAL CORRESPONDENT,
SUSAN CANDIOTTI, HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WITH ALL OF US, SHE'S WORKING
HER SOURCES.
WHAT'S THE LATEST, SUSAN?
>> Reporter: HI, WOLF.
OF COURSE, THE QUESTION IS WHAT
MOVE A 20-YEAR-OLD YOUNG MAN TO
TARGET SO MANY INNOCENT VICTIMS.
INVESTIGATOR ARE LOOKING
EVERYWHERE FOR CLUES.
FOR EXAMPLE, TRYING TO FINE
ANYTHING HE MIGHT HAVE WRITTEN
DOWN, TRYING TO TALK TO FAMILY
AND FRIENDS, EVEN RETRACING HIS
STEPS TO LOOK FOR CLUES.
INVESTIGATORS ARE LEARNING MORE
EACH DAY THAT MAY HAVE LED TO
EXPLAIN WHAT 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM
LANZA LED A VESHS ATTACK.
>> INVESTIGATORS AT THE CRIME
SCENE, THE SCHOOL, AT THE
SECONDA
SECONDARY CRIME SCENE WE
DISCUSSED, THE FEMALE LOCATED,
DECEASED, DID PRODUCE VERY GOOD
EVIDENCE IN THE INVESTIGATION,
THAT OUR INVESTIGATORS WILL BE
ABLE TO USE AND HOPEFULLY
PAINTING A COMPLETE PICTURE AS
TO HOW AND, MORE IMPORTANTLY,
WHY THIS OCCURRED.
>> Reporter: POLICE WON'T SAY
WHAT THE EVIDENCE IS.
HOWEVER, INVESTIGATORS HAVE BEEN
CHECKING OUT GUN RANGES AND
SPORTING GOOD STORES.
THEY FOLLOWED A LEAD, THE
SHOOTER TRIED TO BUY A GUN
TUESDAY AT THIS LOCATION.
AFTER SEARCHING STORE
SURVEILLANCE VIDEOS, THE TIP
DIDN'T PAN OUT.
>> TO DATE ATF HAS NOT UNCOVERED
ANY INFORMATION THAT WOULD
SUBSTANTIATE THE FACT HE TRIED
TO ACQUIRE GUNS RECENTLY.
WE'RE OUT THERE ACTIVELY
INVESTIGATING.
>> Reporter: FEDERAL GUN AGENTS
RECOVERED WEAPONS AT THE HOME
THE SHOOTER SHARED WITH HIS
MOTHER.
THREE MORE GUNS WERE FOUND.
THESE THREE, ALL OLDER, BEING
TRACED.
AT LEAST ONCE HAS BEEN CONNECTED
TO THE MOTHER.
THREE MORE WEAPONS WERE
DISCOVERED WITH THE SHOOTER IN A
CLASSROOM WHERE HE TOOK HIS OWN
LIFE.
ACCORDING TO LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS, THE TWO HANDGUNS AND
SEMIAUTOMATIC LONG GUN, CALLED A
BUSHMASTER WERE BOUGHT LEGALLY
BY HIS MOTHER.
THAT LONG GUN WAS USED TO KILL
SEVERAL VICTIMS.
>> I ONLY DID SEVEN AUTOPSIES.
VICTIMS 3 TO 11, AND I SAW TWO
OF THEM WITH POST-RANGE
SHOOTING.
ALL WOULDN'TS THAT I KNOW OF AT
THIS POINT CAUSED BY THE LONG
WEAPON.
>> Reporter: ONE RELATIVE
DESCRIBES THE SHOOTER AS A VERY
BRIGHT YOUNG MAN.
ONE POINT HOME SCHOOLED BY HIS
MOTHER.
AND A LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIAL
TELLS US THAT THE SHOOTER'S
OLDER BROTHER DESCRIBED TO THEM
THAT HIS YOUNGER BROTHER WAS   T
AUTISTIC, BUT SO FAR NOTHING
ADDS UP TO A MOTIVE.
WOLF?
>> SUSAN CANDIOTTI, THANK VERY
MUCH.
OVER AT THE STRATFORD HIGH
SCHOOL A HALF HOUR OR SO AWAY
FROM WHERE WE ARE HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, THERE'S A
VIGIL UNDER WAY RIGHT NOW.
I WANT TO WATCH AND LISTEN RIGHT
NOW.
♪ AMAZING GRACE
HOW SWEET THE SOUND
THAT SAVED A WRETCH LIKE ME ♪
♪ I ONCE WAS LOST
BUT NOW AM FOUND
WAS BLIND BUT NOW I SEE♪
♪
♪ AMAZING GRACE
HOW SWEET THE SOUND♪
♪
♪ THE TRUTH IS PLAIN TO SEE
SHE WAS SENT TO RESCUE ME ♪
♪ I SEE WHO I WANT TO BE
IN MY DAUGHTER'S EYES ♪
♪ IN MY DAUGHTER'S EYES
EVERYONE IS EQUAL ♪
♪ DARKNESS TURNS TO LIGHT
AND THE WORLD IS AT PEACE ♪
♪ THE MIRACLE GOD GAVE TO ME
GIVES ME STRENGTH ♪
♪ WHEN I AM WEAK
I FIND REASON TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ IN MY DAUGHTER'S EYES
♪ WHEN SHE WRAPS HER HAND
AROUND MY FINGER
IT PUTS A SMILE
ON MY HEART ♪
♪ EVERYTHING BECOMES A LITTLE
CLEAR
I REALIZE WHAT LIFE IS ALL
ABOUT ♪
♪ IT'S HANGING ON WHEN YOUR
HEART
HAS HAD ENOUGH ♪
♪ GIVING MORE WHEN YOU FEEL LIKE
GIVING UP
I SEE THE LIGHT ♪
♪ THAT'S IN MY DAUGHTER'S EYES
IN MY DAUGHTER'S EYES ♪
♪ I CAN SEE THE FUTURE
A REFLECTION OF ♪
♪ WHO I AM AND CHOOSE TO BE
THOUGH SHE'S GONE
SHE GAVE STRENGTH TO HER
FAMILY ♪
♪ WHEN I AM GONE
I HOPE SHE SEES ♪
♪ HOW HAPPY SHE MADE ME
I'LL BE THERE
IN MY DAUGHTER'S EYES♪
>>> JASON CARROLL IS THERE AT
THE HIGH SCHOOL, STRATFORD HIGH
SCHOOL, IN CONNECTICUT.
JASON, SET THE SCENE FOR US.
THIS VIGIL IS SO MOVING, IMAGES
THAT WE'RE SEEING SO POWERFUL
AND REMEMBERING A SPECIAL
PERSON.
>> Reporter: WOLF, THIS IS
EXACTLY HOW VICTORIA, VICKI,
WHAT HER FAMILY CALL HER, HOW
VICKI FAMILY'S WANTED TO
REMEMBER HER.
THIS IS HOW THEY WANTED TO COME
TOGETHER AND GRIEVE.
THIS IS SOMETHING THAT TOOK A
LIFE OF ITS OWN BECAUSE OF
FACEBOOK.
A MESSAGE WENT OUT SAYING THEY
WANTED TO BRING THE COMMUNITY
TOGETHER, WANTED TO BRING PEOPLE
TOGETHER AND TWEETS WENT OUT,
ONE BY VICKI SOTO'S SISTER
SAYING COME TO THE HIGH SCHOOL
HERE AT STRATFORD HIGH SCHOOL
AND THIS IS WHERE WE'RE GOING TO
HAVE A CANDLELIGHT VIGIL.
THIS IS WHERE VICTORIA SOTO
GRADUATED BACK IN 2003.
AND, WOLF, WHEN I SPOKE TO HER
FAMILY, EARLIER TODAY, YOU
REALLY GET MORE OF A PICTURE,
MORE OF A SENSE AS YOU LOOK AT
THE PICTURE THERE ON YOUR
SCREEN, YOU GET A SENSE OF WHO
THIS WOMAN WAS.
THAT PICTURE WAS THE PICTURE
TAKEN FROM THE SCHOOL, SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY.
HER MOTHER JUST GOT THAT PICTURE
LAST WEEK.
ONE OF HER MOTHER'S FAVORITE
PICTURES THAT THAT'S THE PICTURE
HER MOTHER SAYS THIS IS THE
IMAGE WE WANT THE WORLD TO SEE
OF OUR VICTORIA SOTO.
THEY DESCRIBE HER AS A DEDICATED
TEACHER.
A WOMAN WHO DIDN'T CALL HER
STUDENTS STUDENTS.
SHE CALLED THEM, QUOTE, HER
KIDS, EVERY TIME SHE SPOKE ABOUT
THEM.
SHE ACTUALLY HERSELF WANTED TO
BE A TEACHER EVERY SINCE SHE
HERSELF WAS A LITTLE GIRL.
AND SO, IT WAS -- THE FAMILY WAS
ESPECIALLY PROUD WHEN SHE BECAME
A TEACHER.
SHE WAS REALLY THE ROCK OF THE
EXTENDED FAMILY.
SHE WAS THE ONE WHO DID SECRET
SANTA EVERY YEAR DURING THE
HOLIDAYS.
BUT SHE'S JUST REALLY ESPECIALLY
GOING TO BE MISSED.
ALSO HERE THAT YOU SEE HERE IN
THE CROWD ARE HER FAMILY, HER
TWO SISTERS.
SHE'S GOT A SISTER, JULIAN,
ANOTHER SISTER, CARLY, HER
BROTHER CARLO MATTHEW, HER
FATHER, THEY ARE HERE AS WELL.
HER COUSIN HERE, WHO I SPOKE TO
EARLIER TODAY.
A LOT OF THE FOLKS HERE ARE
WEARING GREEN AND THAT'S BECAUSE
GREEN WAS ONE OF VICTORIA'S
FAVORITE COLORS.
THE WORD WENT OUT TODAY, IF
YOU'VE GOT GREEN, WARE A GREEN
HAT, GREEN GLOVES, SWEATER,
ANYTHING PUT IT ON.
THIS IS ANOTHER WAY TO REMEMBER
VICTORIA.
THEY DID NOT WANT HER TO BE
REMEMBERED AS JUST A VICTIM,
WOLF.
THEY WANTED HER TO BE REMEMBERED
AS A DEDICATED TEACHER, A LOVING
SISTER, AND A LOVING DAUGHTER.
WOLF?
>> A STORY, SUCH A STORY OF A
WONDERFUL WOMAN, VICKI SOTO,
FIRST GRADE TEACHER AT THE
SCHOOL, 27 YEARS OLD.
SHE HAD HER STUDENTS HUDDLED
BEHIND HER, TRIED TO PROTECT
THEM, AS JASON'S BEEN TELLING
US.
SHE WAS SHOT AND KILLED AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
JASON, I WANT TO LET OUR VIEWERS
KNOW THAT WE HAVE LEARNED THAT
THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES, PRESIDENT OBAMA, WILL
COME HERE TO NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, TOMORROW.
HE WILL ATTEND THE INTERFAITH
VIGIL THAT WILL TAKE PLACE AT
7:00 P.M., 7:00 P.M. EASTERN
TIME HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES WANTED TO BE HERE.
HE WANTS TO COMFORT THE
FAMILIES.
HE WANTS TO PARTICIPATE IN THIS
INTERFAITH VIGIL THAT WILL TAKE
PLACE HERE IN NEWTOWN TOMORROW
NIGHT.
OBVIOUSLY HE HAS BEEN SHAKEN.
WE ALL SAW WHAT HE SAID
YESTERDAY AT THAT BRIEF
STATEMENT HE MADE IN THE WHITE
HOUSE.
HE BROKE DOWN, STARTED TO CRY,
HOLDING BACK TEARS.
SO THE PRESIDENT WILL BE HERE
TOMORROW NIGHT, 7:00 P.M.
EASTERN FOR THE INTERFAITH VIGIL
HERE IN NEWTOWN.
LET'S GO BACK IN THE MEANTIME TO
THE VIGIL THAT'S TAKING PLACE
RIGHT NOW OVER AT STRATFORD HIGH
SCHOOL.
♪ THE TIME YOU MUST
KEEP ON SMILING
SMILE ♪
♪ WHAT'S THE USE IN CRYING
YOU FIND THAT LIFE IS
STILL WORTHWHILE ♪
♪ IF YOU JUST SMILE
>> LAST SELECTION WILL BE
PERFORMED BY MYSELF.
♪ NEVER DREAMED OF
THE SORROW ♪
♪ I NEVER FELT
I HAVE REASON TO LAMENT ♪
♪ I HOPE I'D NEVER KNOW
HEARTBREAK
HOW I WISH I COULD ♪
♪ CHANGE THE WAY THINGS WENT
I WANTED NOTHING BUT GOODNESS ♪
♪ I WANTED REASON
TO PREVAIL ♪
♪ I WANT ED LIFE TO GO ON
I WANTED DAYS OF PLENTY ♪
♪ BUT I REFUSED TO FEEL
TRAGIC ♪
♪ THERE'S GOT TO BE SOMETHING
ELSE THAT'S MORE THAN
PAIN AND GRIEF ♪
♪ THERE'S GOT TO BE MEANING
MOST OF ALL WHEN A LIFE
HAS BEEN SO BRIEF ♪
♪ I'VE GOT TO LEARN SOMETHING
HOW CAN I GATHER ANY LESS
I WANT LIFE TO GO ON ♪
♪ I WANT ED DAYS OF PLENTY
YOU HAVE TO BELIEVE ♪
♪ THERE IS REASON FOR HOPE
♪ THAT THE ANSWERS WILL COME
YOU CAN'T LET THIS DEFEAT YOU ♪
♪ I WON'T LET THIS DEFEAT YOU
YOU MUST FIGHT TO KEEP ♪
♪ HER THERE WITHIN YOU
SO BELIEVE THAT SHE MATTERED
AND BELIEVE THAT SHE ♪
♪ ALWAYS WILL
SHE WILL ALWAYS BE WITH YOU ♪
♪ SHE'LL BE PART OF THE DAYS
YOU'LL GET TO FILL
SHE WILL LIVE IN YOUR BOUNTY
SHE WILL LIVE ♪
♪ AS YOU CARRY ON YOUR LIFE
THROUGH DAYS OF PLENTY♪
THANK YOU FOR LETTING US BE
HERE.
>>> THIS VIGIL CONTINUES AT
STRATFORD HIGH SCHOOL NOT FAR
AWAY FROM NEWTOWN, WHERE WE ARE.
THE VIJ THGIL THAT WE'RE WATCHI
REMEMBERING VICKI SOTO, ONLY 27
YEARS OLD.
KATE BOLDUAN IS STILL WITH US.
KATE, YOU HAD A CHANCE TO SPEAK
WITH PARENTS WHO ARE FORTUNATE
THEIR LITTLE CHILD SURVIVED, IN
PART THANKS TO VICKI SOTO.
>> Reporter: ABSOLUTELY RIGHT,
WOLF.
THAT'S WHAT THOSE PARENTS SAY.
THIS IS ROBERT AND DIANE
LACOTTI.
THEY NOT ONLY HAVE ONE CHILD AT
SANDY HOOK, TWO CHILDREN AT
SANDY HOOK YESTERDAY, THEIR
DAUGHTER IN SECOND GRADE, THEIR
SON IN FIRST GRADE IN VICTORIA
SOTO'S -- AS WE CONTINUE TO LOOK
AT THESE PICTURES OF THIS VIGIL.
THEIR FIRST GRADE SON, IN HER
CLASS, HE TALKS ABOUT NOT ONLY
BEING ABLE TO ESCAPE BUT BEFORE
THAT, COMING FACE-TO-FACE WITH
THE SHOOTER, WOLF.
>> WHAT HAPPENED WHEN I GOT TO
THE SCHOOL AND REALIZED IT WAS
SANDY HOOK, PULLED DOWN AS FAR
AS I COULD, I COULDN'T GET ALL
THE WAY.
I DROVE OVER THE CURB INTO THE
FIREHOUSE PARKING LOT AND I
SAID, IT'S HERE, IT'S HERE,
THERE'S BEEN A SHOOTING HERE.
AND I SAW -- I SAW THE EMTs
WORKING ON A LITTLE BOY AND I
KNEW IT WASN'T OUR SON I KNEW IT
WAS CLOSE, I RAN TO THE SCHOOL.
YOU KNOW THE CHAOS IS
INDESCRIBABLE.
I MEAN, IT'S LIKE LIVING THROUGH
COLUMBINE, EVERYTHING YOU'VE
SEEN ON TV.
SO AS THE CHILDREN START TO COME
OUT, YOU KNOW, SINGLE TIME,
CLASS BY CLASS, GROUP BY GROUP,
WHEN YOU SEE THEIR TEACHER, I
SAW MY DAUGHTER'S TEACHER, SHE
WASN'T -- MY DAUGHTER WASN'T
WITH HER TEACHER AND I GRABBED
HER TEACH SOMEWHERE ASKED HER
WHERE SHE WAS SHE SAID SHE
DIDN'T KNOW BECAUSE SHE WASN'T
WITH THE CLASS.
SO THE KIDS START TO COME OUT.
WHEN I SAW HER, THE SENSE OF
RELIEF IS INCREDIBLE BUT IT'S
REALLY SHORT-LIVED BECAUSE I
STILL HAVE ONE IN THERE AND I'M
WAITING FOR HIM TO COME.
AND HE DIDN'T COME OUT.
AND I DIDN'T SEE HIS TEACHER AND
I DIDN'T SEE HIS CLASSMATES.
SO AS A PARENT, YOU KNOW, I
HUGGED MADE DAUGHTER AND I SAID,
YOU KNOW, I TOLD HER TO HUG HER
FRIEND IN HER CLASS AND I SAID
GO TO THE FIRE STATION, DADDY'S
COMING.
I'M GOING TO WAIT FOR ADEN.
I'M GOING TO WAIT.
AND HE DIDN'T COME OUT.
SO YOU KNOW, WHEN YOU'RE
STANDING THERE WAITING, AND NO
ONE WILL TELL YOU ANYTHING, IT'S
INDESCRIBABLE FEELING OF
HELPLESSNESS.
YOU KNOW, WE ARE VERY LUCKY
BECAUSE I THINK I WAS THERE AN
HOUR AND THEN THE GROUP STOPPED
COMING AND I JUST KNEW NO ONE
ELZ WAS COMING OUT OF THAT
SCHOOL.
I KNEW IN MY HEART.
I ACTUALLY RECEIVED A TEXT FROM
A FRIEND SAID THAT HE WAS AT THE
POLICE STATION AND HE WAS SAFE
THERE AND HE WAS ONE OF THE
GROUPS OF KIDS THAT RAN THAT GOT
OUT, HAD BEEN PICKED UP.
WHEN WE WENT THERE, AND I SAW
HIM FOR THE FIRST TIME, IT WAS
JUST AN INCREDIBLE FEELING OF
RELIEF AND I FEEL SO BLESSED.
IT'S JUST A FEELING OF BLESSING.
>> A MIRACLE.
>> TRULY IS.
>> ANGELS ON THEIR SHOULDER.
THE CHILDREN GOT OUT OF THE KAS
ROOM.
IT WAS A BLESSING.
INDESCRIBABLE.
>> IT'S AN AMAZING FEELING.
AND YOU FEEL -- YOU FEEL SO
RELIEVED BUT AT THE SAME TIME
YOU KNOW THAT OTHERS CAN'T SHARE
THAT FEELING.
AND YOU JUST -- YOUR HEART
DOESN'T KNOW WHICH DIRECTION TO
GO.
THEIR FRIENDS, THEIR NEIGHBORS.
>> THESE ARE CHILDREN THAT OUR
CHILDREN WENT TO PRESCHOOL WITH,
KNOWN SINCE THEY WERE 2 YEARS
OLD 3 YEAR OLD, SO THE MAGNITUDE
OF WHAT'S HAPPENED, NOT JUST FOR
US BUT FOR EVERYONE IN THIS
COMMUNITY, HASN'T EVEN BEEN FELT
YET.
THE CHILDREN WILL LEARN ABOUT
THEIR FRIENDS AND THEIR TEACHER
AND OTHERS THAT THEY KNOW AND,
YOU KNOW, WE, AS PARENTS, NEED
TO DO THE BEST TO PREPARE OUR
CHILDREN FOR THAT AND EXPLAIN IN
THE BEST WAY WE CAN THAT MAKES
SENSE TO THEM WHAT'S HAPPENED
AND HOW TO KIND OF HELP THEM
THROUGH THAT PROCESS.
>> FROM WHAT YOU'VE BEEN TOLD BY
YOUR SON AND WHAT YOU KNOW NOW,
WHAT HAPPENED?
>> ACCORDING TO ADEN, THEY WENT
THROUGH A NORMAL DAY.
THEY DID THEIR CIRCLE TIME,
WHERE THEY INTRODUCE EACH OTHER,
THEY DID THEIR MESSAGE --
>> OVER THE LOUDSPEAKER.
>> AND THEY WERE DOING THEIR
ANNOUNCEMENT OVER THE
LOUDSPEAKER.
AND THAT'S WHEN THEY HEARD
NOISES THAT HE DESCRIBED AS
INITIALLY THEY THOUGHT WERE
HAMMERS FALLING.
THEN THEY REALIZED THAT IT WAS
GUNSHOTS.
AND MISS SOTO, ADEN'S TEACHER,
HAD THE PRESENCE OF MIND TO MOVE
ALL OF THE CHILDREN TO A
DISTANCE AWAY FROM THE DOOR ON
THE SIDE OF THE ROOM FURTHEST
AWAY FROM THE DOOR AND THAT'S
WHEN THE GUNMAN BURST IN, DID
NOT SAY A WORD.
NO FACIAL EXPRESSIONS.
AND PROCEEDED TO SHOOT THEIR
TEACHER.
AT THAT TIME, THE CHILDREN FROM
AN EARLY AGE ARE TAUGHT, WHEN
THEY SEE A PERSON WITH A GUN,
YOU RUN AND YOU CALL 911.
AND THEY PRACTICE THAT IN SCHOOL
WITH THEIR FIRE AND EMERGENCY
DRILLS AND EVERYTHING.
WE'RE VERY LUCKY THAT ALL OF THE
CHILDREN, MY SON INCLUDED, HAD
THE PRESENCE OF MIND TO REACT
APPROPRIATELY AND THEY BASICALLY
RAN RIGHT PAST THE GUNMAN OUT
THE DOOR.
>> RAN PAST THE GUNMAN?
>> HE'S STANDING IN THE DOOR AND
THEY RAN PAST HIM AND RAN DOWN
THE HALLWAY AND THEY'RE ONE OF
THE CLOSEST ROOMS TO THE MAIN
ENTRANCE, AND ADEN WAS -- HAD
THE PRESENCE OF MIND TO HOLD THE
DOOR FOR ONE OF HIS CLASSMATES.
THERE WAS ANOTHER CLASSMATE THAT
WAS BEHIND AND WAITED FOR HIM
AND THEY ALL RAN TO THE ROAD,
THE MAN ROAD, ALL THE WAY DOWN.
AND WHERE THEY MET A WOMAN WHO
IS AN ANGEL TO US, WHO TOOK THEM
INTO HER VAN AND TOOK THEM TO
THE POLICE STATION.
>> HOW DID YOUR SON, HE'S 6
YEARS OLD, HAVE THE PRESENCE OF
MIND, FACED NOT ONLY BY SEEING
THIS HORRIFIC ACT HAPPEN IN
FRONT OF HIM, BUT THEN HAVE THE
PRESENCE OF MIND TO RUN PAST
THIS PERSON AND TO SAFETY?
>> I THINK IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO
HONESTLY KNOW WHAT WAS GOING
THROUGH HIS MIND.
YOU KNOW, IT'S SAD TO SAY THAT
IN TODAY'S WORLD I DO WATCH THE
NEWS WITH THE KIDS, I DO DISCUSS
ALL OF THE THINGS THAT HAPPEN,
AND HAVE TOLD THEM, YOU KNOW,
THINKING FROM A HIGH SCHOOL OR
COLLEGE PERSPECTIVE, IF ANYBODY
EVER COMES INTO YOUR CLASSROOM
WITH A GUN, YOU JUST RUN.
AND I'VE SAID THAT TO THEM
COUNTLESS TIMES, JUST -- YOU
JUST RUN.
AND SO I -- I'M SURE -- I'D LIKE
TO THINK THAT PART OF THAT IS
DEEP DOWN INSIDE, MY SON AND HE
KNEW HE HAD THE PRESENCE OF NIND
DO THAT.
AND I THINK PART OF IT WAS JUST
THIS FIGHT OR FLIGHT RESPONSE,
THIS INSTINCT THAT TOLD HIM AND
OTHER STUDENTS IN THAT ROOM TO
JUST LEAVE.
AND I THINK MAYBE BECAUSE OF THE
WAY THAT THINGS PLAYED OUT, HOW
THE GUNMAN CAME IN AND SHOT
THEIR TEACHER FIRST, I KNOW THEY
WOULD HAVE LOOKED TO HER FOR
GUIDANCE AND WITHOUT HER, TO
TELL THEM WHAT TO DO, THEY JUST
RAN.
AND IT'S HONESTLY A MIRACLE THAT
I'M ABLE TO HAVE -- WE'RE ABLE
TO HAVE THIS CONVERSATION WITH
YOU AND WITH OUR SON STILL WITH
US.
>> DO YOU THINK HE KNOWS WHAT
THE -- THAT SHE LIKELY DID NOT
MAKE IT?
>> HE KEEPS ASKING ABOUT HER.
HE'S REASSURING HIMSELF THAT
SHE'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
HE REALLY, REALLY, REALLY CARED
ABOUT HIS TEACHER.
HE WAS VERY CLOSE WITH HER AND
SHE REALLY LOVED THAT CLASS.
HE KEEPS SAYING, I REALLY HOPE
SHE'S OKAY, I HOPE IT'S NOT HER.
HE KNOWS THAT SHE'S BEEN HURT
BUT HE DOESN'T KNOW THE END
RESULT.
HE KNOWS THE KIDS THAT HE SAW
GETTING SHOT.
HE DOESN'T KNOW THE OUTCOME.
I THINK HE'S REASSURING HIMSELF
IN HIS 6-YEAR-OLD MIND, I KNOW
HE'S PROCESSING IT, BUT I THINK
HE'S REASSURING HIMSELF.
I THINK HE'S TELLING HIMSELF
THAT IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
>> WHAT WAS YESTERDAY SUPPOSED
TO BE LIKE?
>> I WAS SUPPOSED TO GO THERE
2:00 AND BUILD A GINGERBREAD
HOUSE, YOU KNOW?
THIS HE SOMETHING WE DO AS
PARENTS.
ALL PARENTS IN THIS COMMUNITY
VERY MUCH INVOLVED.
WE GO IN AND READ BOOKS.
DIANE'S ACTIVE IN VOLUNTEERING
THERE.
WE KNOW THE TEACHERS.
WE KNOW A LOT OF THE KIDS.
SO 2:00 I WAS SUPPOSED TO GO AND
BUILD A GINGERBREAD HOUSE.
THAT'S WHAT AIDEN'S CLASS WAS
DOING.
>> STARTS OUT LIKE ANY OTHER
DAY.
>> ROUTINE.
>> WORKING FROM HOME, I HAD
MEETINGS AND GOING TO THE GYM
AND I WAS SUPPOSED TO GO TO
AIDEN'S CLASS BUT I ASKED ROBERT
IF HE HAD MEETINGS AND I SAID
WHY DON'T YOU GO, AIDEN WILL BE
EXCITED.
HE COULDN'T WAIT FOR DADDY TO
COME.
START OFF LIKE ANY OTHER DAY.
>> Reporter: WHAT WAS LAST NIGHT
LIKE WHEN YOU FINALLY HAVE YOUR
FAMILY BACK TOGETHER AND YOU
COME HOME?
>> THE DAY WAS HOURLESS.
I COULDN'T TELL YOU WHAT TIME IT
WAS.
IT WAS -- TIME ALMOST STOOD
STILL BUT AT THE SAME TIME JUST
KEPT PROGRESSING.
HAVING THE KIDS, WE STAYED SO
CLOSE TOGETHER.
WE SAT ON THE COUCH ALL NIGHT.
THE KIDS, WE TRIED TO KEEP THEM
PROTECTED, LETTING THEM WATCH
WHATEVER THEY WANTED TO ON
TELEVISION AND WE STAYED REALLY,
REALLY CLOSE.
WE ALL SLEPT IN THE SAME ROOM
LAST NIGHT.
>> Reporter: DAN, WHAT'S THAT
MOMENT LIKE WHEN YOU KNOW HOW
YOUR DAY WENT AND THEN YOU GOT
EVERYONE TOGETHER?
>> YOU BREAK -- FOR ME I'VE BEEN
A VERY EMOTIONAL PERSON AND YOU
JUST -- I JUST BROKE DOWN
BECAUSE I'M SOBBING BECAUSE I'M
RELIEVED, BECAUSE I HAVE MY SON
BUT I'M SOBBING BECAUSE I KNOW
THAT OTHERS DO NOT AND THAT
ADULTS WERE LOST, CHILDREN WERE
LOST, PEOPLE ARE SUFFERING FROM
SUCH AN INCREDIBLE,
INDESCRIBABLE LOSS THAT THE ONLY
THING I KNOW HOW TO DO TO
PROCESS IT IS LET THAT -- THOSE
FEELINGS OUT.
AND I JUST STARTED CRYING.
>> WE DIDN'T KNOW WHAT TO
EXPECT.
WE DIDN'T KNOW HOW -- IF THEY
WERE GOING TO WAKE UP AND, YOU
KNOW, WITH A NIGHTMARE, AND
HAPPILY TODAY ACTUALLY SLEPT
WELL AND WE ALL -- THE KIDS
SLEPT WELL.
>> I DIDN'T SLEEP.
>> YOU PROCESS THINGS.
YOU KEEP REPLAYING WHAT OUR
SON -- WHAT WENT THROUGH HIS
MIND AND WHAT HAPPENED AND I
DON'T THINK AS ADULTS WE CAN
EVEN POSSIBLY IMAGINE WHAT ANY
CHILD SAW THAT DAY ESPECIALLY NO
LESS OUR SON.
SO WE WEREN'T SURE WHAT TO
EXPECT.
THEY WOKE UP HAPPY.
WHAT WE'RE TRYING TO DO AS
PARENTS IS PROJECT A SENSE OF
NORMALCY AND A SENSE OF ROUTINE.
>> A SENSE OF SAFETY.
>> SAFETY.
>> BECAUSE HE -- WE HAD TO PUT
THE SIGN OUT IN THE FRONT TODAY
ASKING PEOPLE NOT TO RING THE
DOORBELL BECAUSE HE STILL HASN'T
INTERNALIZED THE FACT THAT THIS
GUNMAN, THIS BAD GUY, IS GONE
AND HE WANTS TO KNOW IF THERE
ARE MORE BAD GUYS IN THE WORLD.
AND I DON'T KNOW HOW TO ANSWER
THAT QUESTION PROPERLY.
AND SO WHEN SOMEONE RINGS THE
DOORBELL HE THINKS IT'S HIM
COMING BACK, COMING FOR HIM.
SO HE -- HE -- SO I THINK OUR
BIGGEST CONCERN NOW IS MAKING
SURE THAT WE HANDLE HIS
SENSITIVE NATURE PROPERLY AND
CAREFULLY AND SUPPORT HIM AND
SUPPORT OUR DAUGHTER BECAUSE
SHE, AGAIN, DOES PROCESS THINGS
VERY DIFFERENTLY THAN HE DOES.
SO THAT'S OUR JOB AS PARENTS
NOW, TO STAY CLOSE TO THEM, HOLD
THEM, HUG THEM, LOVE THEM, AND
LET THEM KNOW THAT THEY ARE
SAFE.
>> Reporter: I'LL TELL YOU,
WOLF, ROBERT AND DIANE, THEY DID
NOT WANT THEIR CHILDREN TO BE ON
CAMERA.
THEY ARE STILL PROCESSING
EVERYTHING THAT HE HAVE GONE
THROUGH.
BUT I DID HAVE THE OPPORTUNITY
TO SPEND TIME NOT ONLY WITH
SWRO
ROBERT AND DIANE BUT WITH THEIR
TWO CHILDREN.
AIDEN AND HIS SISTER SEEM IN
VERY HIGH SPIRITS, SEEM LIKE TWO
KIDS ON A SATURDAY MORNING.
CLEARLY THEY ARE SHAKEN AFTER
EVERYTHING THEY'VE EXPERIENCED.
BOTH PARENTS SAID TO ME, AS HARD
AS IT IS FOR THIS FAMILY AND
WHAT THEY'VE BEEN THROUGH, THEY
KNOW THERE ARE MANY MORE
FAMILIES THAT ARE NOT ABLE TO
HUG THEIR CHILDREN TONIGHT AND
THEIR HEARTS ARE BREAKING FOR
THEM AND GO OUT TO THOSE
FAMILIES.
WOLF?
>> OUR HEARTS ARE BREAKING FOR
THEM AS WELL.
KATE, THANKS SO MUCH FOR SHARING
THAT WITH ALL OF OUR VIEWERS.
WE HAVE SOMETHING VERY SPECIAL
WHEN WE COME BACK.
ROBBIE PARKER, THE FATHER OF
6-YEAR-OLD EMILY PARKER, SHE WAS
KILLED YESTERDAY.
HE IS NOW SPEAKING OUT.
WE'RE GOING TO HEAR WHAT HE'S
SAYING ABOUT HIS BEAUTIFUL
6-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER WHEN WE COME
BACK.e.
But when I was in an accident...
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
Information on my phone.
Connection to doctors who
get where I'm from.
And tools to estimate what
my care may cost.
So I never missed a beat.
We're more than 78,000
people looking out for
more than 70
million Americans.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.
BOPRODUCTIVITY UP, COSTS DOWN,
THTIME TO MARKET REDUCED...
THOSE ARE GOOD THINGS.
UPSTAIRS, THEY WILL SEE FANTASY.
NOT FANTASY... LOGISTICS.
UPS CAME IN, ANALYZED OUR SUPPLY
CHAIN, INVENTORY SYSTEMS...
UPS?
UPS.
NOT FANTASY?
WHO WOULD HAVE THOUGHT?
I DID.
WE DID, BOB. WE DID.
GOT IT.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL TRAVEL
HERE TO CONNECTICUT TOMORROW TO
JOIN IN REMEMBERING AND IN
MOURNING THE VICTIMS OF THE
SECOND DEADLIEST SHOOTING
INCIDENT IN U.S. HISTORY AT A
SCHOOL.
A WHITE HOUSE STATEMENT SAYS THE
PRESIDENT WILL SPEAK AT AN
INTERFAITH VIGIL FOR FAMILIES OF
THE VICTIMS AS WELL AS FAMILIES
FROM SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, 7:00 P.M., SUNDAY HERE
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE HAVE BEEN WATCHING A VIGIL
THIS HOUR FOR ONE VICTIM, A
TEACHER, WHO DIED TRYING TO SAVE
HER STUDENTS.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT VICTORIA
SOTO.
TODAY WE LEARNED THE NAMES OF
ALL SIX ADULTS AND 20 CHILDREN
GUNNED DOWN AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
WE ALSO LEARNED MORE ABOUT HOW
THEY DIED.
POLICE SAY THREE GUNS WERE FOUND
AT THE SCENE NEXT TO THE BODY OF
THE SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA.
BUT THE MEDICAL EXAMINER SAYS
ALL WOUNDS HE KNOWS OF WERE
CAUSED BY WHAT HE CALLS THE LONG
WEAPON, THAT RIFLE, THAT WE'RE
TALKING ABOUT.
THAT WOULD BE THE MODIFIED
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE THAT'S A
CIVILIAN VERSION OF THE MILITARY
M-16.
ONE OF THE VICTIMS OF THE
NEWTOWN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
MASSACRE WAS A 6-YEAR-OLD GIRL
NAMED EMILY PARKER.
HER FATHER GAVE A HEART
WRENCHING NEWS CONFERENCE A
LITTLE WHILE AGO.
LISTEN TO THIS.
MY DAUGHTER EMILIE WOULD BE ONE
OF THE FIRST ONES TO BE STANDING
AND GIVING HER LOVE AND SUPPORT
TO ALL THOSE VICTIMS.
BECAUSE THAT'S THE TYPE OF
PERSON THAT SHE IS.
NOT BECAUSE OF ANY PARENTING
THAT MY WIFE AND I COULD HAVE
DONE.
BUT BECAUSE THOSE WERE THE GIFTS
THAT WERE GIVEN TO HER BY HER
HEAVENLY FATHER.
AS THE DEEP PAIN BEGINS TO
SETTLE INTO OUR HEARTS, WE FIND
COMFORT REFLECTING ON THE
INCREDIBLE PERSON THAT EMILIE
WAS, AND HOW MANY LIVES SHE WAS
ABLE TO TOUCH IN HER SHORT TIME
HERE ON EARTH.
EMILIE WAS BRIGHT, CREATIVE AND
VERY LOVING.
EMILIE WAS ALWAYS WILLING TO TRY
NEW THINGS, OTHER THAN FOOD.
SHE LOVED TO USE HER TALENTS TO
IT TOUCH THE LIVES OF EVERYONE
SHE CAME INTO CONTACT WITH.
SHE WAS AN EXCEPTIONAL ARTIST,
AND SHE ALWAYS CARRIED AROUND
HER MARKERS AND PENCILS SO SHE
NEVER MISSED AN OPPORTUNITY TO
DRAW A PICTURE OR MAKE A CARD
FOR THOSE AROUND HER.
I CAN'T COUNT THE NUMBER OF
TIMES EMILIE NOTICED SOMEONE
FEELING SAD OR FRUSTRATED AND
WOULD RUSH TO FIND A PIECE OF
PAPER TO DRAW THEM A PICTURE OR
TO WRITE THEM AN ENCOURAGING
NOTE.
EMILIE'S CARD-MAKING WAS
EXPRESSED BEAUTIFULLY THIS LAST
OCTOBER WHEN SHE PLACED A VERY
SPECIAL CARD SHE HAD MADE INTO
THE CASKET WITH HER GRANDPA, WHO
ALSO JUST RECENTLY DIED OF A
TRAGIC ACCIDENT.
EMILIE WAS A MENTOR TO HER TWO
LITTLE SISTERS IN DELIGHTING AND
TEACHING THEM HOW TO READ, DANCE
AND FIND THE SIMPLE JOYS IN
LIFE.
EMLIE'S LAUGHTER WAS INFECTIOUS,
AND ALL THOSE WHO HAD THE FLEESH
MEET HER WOULD AGREE THIS
WORLD'S A BERT PLACE BECAUSE SHE
HAS BEEN IN IT.
I HAVE BEEN TEACHING HER
PORTUGUESE.
OUR LAST CONVERSATION WAS IN
AND SHE'S -- SHE TOLD ME GOOD
MORNING AND ASKED HOW I WAS
DOING AND I SAID I WAS DOING
WELL.
SHE SAID SHE LOVED ME, I GAVE
HER A KISS AND I WAS OUT THE
DOOR.
THEY WERE BORN WITHIN THREE
YEARS OF EACH OTHER.
BY LAW THEY'RE VERY CLOSE.
SHE WAS TEACHING MY MIDDLE
DAUGHTER TO READ.
SHE WOULD HELP ME YOUNGEST
DAUGHTER HOW TO MAKE THINGS, DO
CRAFTS.
THEY LOOKED UP TO HER.
THEY LOOKED TO HER WHEN THEY
NEEDED COMFORT.
USUALLY THAT'S -- THAT'S SAVED
FOR HER MOM AND DAD BUT IT WAS
REALLY SWEET TO SEE THE TIMES
ONE OF THEM WOULD FALL OR GET
THEIR FEELINGS HURT, HOW THEY
WOULD RUN TO EMILIE GET SUPPORT
AND HUGS AND KISSES.
SHE WAS THE TYPE OF INSURGENT
COULD LIGHT UP THE ROOM.
SHE ALWAYS HAD SOMETHING KIND TO
SAY ABOUT ANYBODY.
HER LOVE AND STRENGTH SHE GAVE
US AND THE EXAMPLE SHE SHOWED TO
US IS REMARKABLE.
SHE IS AN INCREDIBLE PERSON.
AND I'M SO BLESSED TO BE HER
DAD.
>> ROBBIE PARKER, 30-YEAR-OLD
FATHER OF LITTLE EMILIE PARKER,
WHO WAS MURDERED YESTERDAY HERE
AT THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
ANDERSON COOPER'S ON THE SCENE.
I DON'T FOE WHAT ELSE TO SAY
AFTER HEARING A DAD LIKE THAT.
>> YEAH.
IT'S ALL JUST BEYOND WORDS
REALLY.
AND I SAID THIS LAST NIGHT, I
FEEL LIKE ALL OF THE WORDS THAT
WE SPEAK AND ALL OF THE WORDS
THAT CAN BE SPOKEN ARE JUST --
IT SEEMS SO SMALL IN THE FACE OF
THIS HORROR.
>> HE WORKS IN A HOSPITAL.
HE'S A PHYSICIAN'S ASSISTANT.
HE DEALS WITH SAVING PEOPLE'S
LIVES.
HE'S AT WORK AND ALL OF A SUDDEN
HE GETS A CALL.
THERE'S A PROBLEM.
>> UNIMAGINABLE.
>> YOU KNOW, ALL DAY LONG HERE
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN GATHERING AND
IN SPOTS, IMPROMPTU SPOTS,
PUBLIC VIGILS, OTHER TIMES ON A
STREET CORNER.
EVERYBODY WANTS TO TALK ABOUT
WHERE THEY WERE, WHAT THEY
HEARD, WHO THEY KNEW.
AND IT'S REALLY EXTRAORDINARY
FEELING HERE RIGHT NOW.
I MEAN THIS IS A COMMUNITY
WHICH -- IT SOUND CLICHE -- BUT
IT'S A COMMUNITY TRYING TO COME
TOGETHER, TRYING TO HELP ONE
ANOTHER.
AND IT'S AN EXTRAORDINARY THING
TO WITNESS.
>> IT HAPPENS THE WEEK BEFORE
CHRISTMAS.
YOU KNOW, PEOPLE HAVE TO SAY TO
THEMSELVES, HOW COULD THIS
HAPPEN IN OUR LITTLE COMMUNITY
HERE, A SMALL CITY, SMALL TOWN,
20,000 PEOPLE, NOT FAR FROM DAN
BURY, AS I WALK AROUND, PEOPLE
DON'T KNOW WHAT TO SAY.
>> YEAH.
AND I MEAN, THIS IS THE KIND
OF -- I MEAN A PARENT NEVER GETS
OVER THE LOSS OF A CHILD,
ESPECIALLY TO HAVE IT AROUND THE
HOLIDAYS AND EACH YEAR THAT
REMAINDER AROUND THIS TIME, WHEN
EVERYONE ELSE IS CELEBRATING.
I THINK PEOPLE IN THIS COMMUNITY
WILL NEVER FORGET THAT AND EACH
HOLIDAY A REMEMBRANCE OF THOSE
WHOSE LIVES WERE LOST.
>> I GOT IN FRONT OF ME HERE,
THIS IS PAINFUL IF YOU LOOK AT
THIS.
THIS IS THE LIST OF THE VICTIMS
THE STATE POLICE RELEASED --
>> HORRIFIC.
>> THE 30 PEOPLE -- EXCUSE ME 26
PEOPLE WHO WERE KILLED AT THE
SCHOOL.
SIX ADULTS AND WE SEE THEIR
NAMES AND THEIR AGES, 29, 47,
52, 30, 56, AND 27.
BUT THEN YOU SEE THE NAMES OF
THE CHILDREN AND ALL OF THEM, 20
KIDS, EITHER 6 OR 7 YEARS OLD,
CHARLOTTE, 6, DANIEL, 7, OLIVIA,
6, JOSEPHINE, 7, ANNA, 6, DYLAN,
6.
I MEAN YOU SEE THESE NAMES.
YOU GO DOWN, JESSICA, 6,
BENJAMIN, 6.
>> TO SEE PHOTOGRAPHS THAT THE
PARENTS ARE RELEASING.
WE'RE ONLY SHOWING PHOTOGRAPHS
OF CHILDN THAT THE FAMILIES
WANT YOU TO SEE AND WANT YOU TO
KNOW.
OBVIOUSLY OUT OF SENSE TEVTY.
WE'VE SEEN THESE SHOOTINGS
BEFORE, TERRIBLY ENOUGH AND
OFTENTIMES IT'S ADULTS THAT
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT.
BUT TO SEE -- AGAIN TO SEE THAT
LITTLE GIRL'S FACE WHILE HER
FATHER'S TALKING ABOUT HER,
IT'S -- IT IS STUNNING.
>> HE WANTED TO GO OUT AND MAKE
THAT STATEMENT.
HE WANTED TO REMEMBER HIS
BEAUTIFUL DAUGHTER EMILIE, HE
HAS TWO OTHER KIDS, 2 AND 4, SHE
WAS 6, AND HE WANTED TO MAKE A
STATEMENT, ANSWER QUESTIONS.
AND YOU KNOW YOU AND I HAVE
COVERED THESE EVENTS BEFORE,
VIRGINIA TECH I REMEMBER PARENTS
WANTED TO SPEAK ABOUT THEIR SONS
OR DAUGHTERS WHO WERE MURDERED.
>> OFTENTIMES PEOPLE WANT YOU TO
KNOW WHO THEIR CHILD WAS AND
WANT YOU TO KNOW WHAT THEIR
CHILD BUT WAS ABOUT AND WHAT
THEIR CHILD WAS LIKE.
FOR SOME IT HELPS FOR OTHERS IT
DOESN'T HELP TO TALK, AND WE
CERTAINLY UNDERSTAND THAT AND
BEING VERY SENSITIVE IN GIVING
PEOPLE PRIVACY THAT THEY WANT
AND DESERVE.
FOR THOSE WHO WANT TO TALK, IT
CAN I DON'T KNOW THAT IT HELPS
BUT IT'S -- IT'S ONE STEP.
>> WE'VE TOLD ALL OF OUR
PRODUCERS, ALL OF OUR STAFF, YOU
KNOW, WE'RE NOT GOING TO TRY TO
CONVINCE PEOPLE, IF THEY DON'T
WANT TO, THEY DON'T HAVE TO.
IF THEY WANT TO, THEY'RE MORE
THAN WELCOME.
WE'D LIKE TO HEAR.
>> IT'S TIMES LIKE THIS, FOR
PEOPLE WATCH, OTHER PARTS OF THE
COUNTRY MIGHT NOT UNDERSTAND WHY
SOMEBODY MIGHT DO A PRESS
CONFERENCE OR DO A STATEMENT.
PEOPLE REALLY WANT, IN THEIR
GRIEF, THEY WANT YOU TO KNOW
ABOUT WHO THEIR LOVED WITHIN WAS
AND THEY KNOW THE THOUGHTS AND
PRAYERS OF SO MANY AROUND THE
WORLD ARE WITH THEM RIGHT NOW.
THEY WANT PEOPLE TO SHARE IN
THAT.
>> NOW WE KNOW THE PRESIDENT
WILL COME HERE AND SHARE HIS
THOUGHTS, NOT ONLY WITH THE
PEOPLE HERE.
HE'S GOING TO TRY TO COMFORT
THEM.
BUT HE'S GOING TO TRY TO COMFORT
A NATION THAT'S GRIEVING RIGHT
NOW.
>> HE'LL BE MEETING WITH
FAMILIES AND ALSO FIRST
RESPONDERS.
OF COURSE THINK ABOUT THOSE
FIRST RESPONDERS AND WHAT THEY
WITNESSED AND HAVE BEEN DEALING
WITH AND THEY NEED AS MUCH
COMFORT FOR THE THINGS THAT THEY
HAVE SEEN IN THESE LAST 24, 36
HOURS.
>> YOU'LL PICK UP COVERAGE AT
THE TOP OF THE HOUR.
YOU'RE HERE FOR THE DURATION,
JUST LIKE ME.
>> YEAH.
>> ANDERSON, THANKS VERY MUCH.
WE'LL TAKE A QUICK BREAK.
MORE SPECIAL COVERAGE AFTER
THIS.
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS KAREN AND JEREMIAH.
THEY DON'T KNOW IT YET,
BUT THEY'RE GONNA FALL IN LOVE,
GET MARRIED,
HAVE A COUPLE OF KIDS,
[ children laughing ]
MOVE TO THE COUNTRY,
AND LIVE A LONG, HAPPY LIFE
TOGETHER
WHERE THEY ALMOST NEVER FIGHT
ABOUT MONEY.
[ dog barks ]
BECAUSE RIGHT AFTER
THEY GET MARRIED,
THEY'LL FIND
SOME RETIREMENT PEOPLE
WHO ARE PAID ON SALARY,
NOT COMMISSION.
THEY'LL GET
STRAIGHTFORWARD GUIDANCE
AND BE ABLE TO FOCUS ON OTHER
THINGS, LIKE EACH OTHER,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
>>> RELATIVES OF THE 20-YEAR-OLD
GUNMAN, ADAM LANZA, GIVING US
ADDITIONAL INSIGHT WHO HE WAS.
HIS AUNT, WHO LIVES IN ILLINOIS,
SPOKE OUT A LITTLE WHILE AGO.
>> I HAD THE TV ON YESTERDAY
MORNING AND THAT'S HOW I FOUND
OUT ABOUT IT.
I TRIED TO CONNECT THE DOTS.
THEY LISTED RYAN, THE ABLE
DIDN'T AGREE.
I HAVE A SON, MICHAEL, A COUPLE
YEARS OLDER THAN RYAN AND WHEN
THEY SAID THE AGE AND THE NAME,
IT DIDN'T CLICK BUT THE LOCATION
DID.
AND IT WAS REVEALED IT WASN'T
RYAN, HE WAS NOW 24.
THEN IT CLICK, YEAH, THAT'S THE
RIGHT AGE OF RYAN.
I COULDN'T IMAGINE RYAN DOING
SUCH A THING HE'S TOO -- TOO
WELL EDUCATED.
WORKS IN NEW YORK CITY.
HE'S A CPA.
HE'S GOT IT TOGETHER.
RYAN, HE WAS DIFFERENT, HE WAS
QUIET.
NICE KID.
GOOD KID.
I MEAN HE WAS DEFINITELY THE
CHALLENGE OF THE FAMILY IN THAT
HOUSE.
EVERY FAMILY HAS ONE.
I HAVE ONE.
THEY HAVE ONE.
BUT NEVER IN TROUBLE WITH THE
LAW.
NEVER IN TROUBLE WITH ANYTHING.
YOU KNOW.
>> DID YOU START MAKING CALLS
REACHING OUT?
WHAT POINT DID YOU START -- WHEN
YOU REALIZED --
>> I CALLED MY HUSBAND IN NORTH
CAROLINA, I SAID HAVE YOU HEARD
THE NEWS?
I SAID YOU NEED TO LITTEN TO IT.
I WAS GETTING READY TO HEAD TO
THE AIRPORT TO PICK UP MY
COLLEGE -- COMING HOME FROM
COLLEGE.
AND I ASKED HIM WHAT HE KNEW.
HE HEARD ABOUT IT BUT DIDN'T
KNOW THE NAMES.
SO I SAID YOU NEED TO LISTEN TO
THE RADIO ON THE WAY HOME.
OF COURSE I LOST IT.
THIS POINT I WAS HEAR, NANCY WAS
NOT ONLY GONE, PJ. -- WE CALLED
HIM PJ, HIS NAME'S PETER --
>> WE LOST HIM.
>> YOU JUST SENT AN E-MAIL?
>> I DID, YESTERDAY, WE HAD BEEN
IN TOUCH.
THOUGH THEY DIVORCED WE WERE
STILL FRIENDS.
>> WHAT WERE YOU CHITCHATTING
ABOUT?
>> THINGS IN GENERAL, LIFE,
KIDS.
WHAT ARE YOUR KIDS UP TO?
>> TEXTING.
>> I SENT HER ONE YESTERDAY
BEFORE I FOUND THIS OUT.
>> WHEN YOU WERE HAVING THESE --
DID SHE EXPRESS HER CONCERNS
ABOUT HER SON?
I MEAN, WHAT HAVE YOU BEEN ABLE
TO PUT TOGETHER NOW THAT YOU
THINK BACK ON WHO HE WAS AND THE
PROBLEMS HE WAS HAVING?
>> I KNOW SHE HAD ISSUES WITH
SCHOOL.
SHE CONVENIENT
EVENTUALLY WOUND UP HOME
SCHOOLING HIM.
SHE BATTLED WITH THE DISTRICT.
I DON'T KNOW IF IT WAS BEHAVIOR,
LEARNING DISABILITIES.
HE WAS A BRIGHT BOY.
HE WAS SMART.
>> DID SHE SHARE WITH YOU --
>> NO, SHE DIDN'T.
>> NO VIOLENCE TOWARD HER?
>> NO.
IF HE DID, SHE WOULDN'T TOLERATE
IT.
IF THEY NEEDED HELP THEY WOULD
HAVE GOTTEN IT.
THEY WERE THE TYPE OF PARENTS,
EVEN WHILE MARRIED OR SEPARATED,
IF THE KIDS HAD A NEED, THEY
WOULD DEFINITELY FILL IT.
>> WE'VE JUST RECEIVED A
STATEMENT COURTESY OF OUR
AFFILIATE WFSB, A STATEMENT FROM
THE FATHER OF ADAM FATHER OF
ADAM LANZA WHO WENT INTO THE
SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
AND KILLED 26 PEOPLE.
A STATEMENT FROM PETER LANZA,
JUST RELEASED.
OUR HEARTS GO OUT TO THE FAMILY
AND FRIENDS WHO LOST LOVED ONES
AND TO ALL THOSE WHO WERE
INJURED.
OUR FAMILY IS GRIEVING ALONG
WITH ALL THOSE WHO HAVE BEEN
AFFECTED BY THIS ENORMOUS
TRAGEDY.
NO WORDS CAN TRULY EXPRESS HOW
HEART BROKEN WE ARE.
WE ARE IN A STATE OF DISBELIEF
IN TRYING TO FIND WHATEVER
ANSWERS WE CAN.
WE, TOO, ARE ASKING WHY.
WE HAVE COOPERATED FULLY WITH
LAW ENFORCEMENT AND WILL
CONTINUE TO DO SO.
LIKE SO MANY OF YOU, WE ARE
SADDENED AND STRUGGLING TO MAKE
SENSE OF WHAT HAS TRANSPIRED.
THAT HAVE STATEMENT JUST COMING
IN FROM PETER LANZA, THE FATHER
OF ADAM LANZA, THE SHOOTER IN
THIS HORRIFIC, HORRIFIC CASE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA TEARFULLY SPOKE
ABOUT THE MASSACRE YESTERDAY.
HE CALLED FOR, QUOTE, A
MEANINGFUL ACTION TO PREVENT
SIMILAR TRAGEDY DPIPS DIDN'T
SPELL OUT, THOUGH, WHAT SHOULD
BE DONE.
I ASKED THE CONNECTICUT SENATOR,
RICHARD BLOOMENTHAL EARLIER
TODAY, WHAT HE EXPECTS TO
HAPPEN.
>> WE'RE GOING TO GO BACK TO
WASHINGTON, THE UNITED STATES,
NEW FEDERAL LEGISLATION NEEDED
TO TIGHTEN UP GUN CONTROL IN THE
UNITED STATES?
>> YOU KNOW, WOLF, THAT IS A
CONVERSATION I AM GOING TO HAVE
WITH MY COLLEAGUES.
TODAY I'M NOT GOING TO DISCUSS
IT OUT OF RESPECT TO THE
FAMILIES.
AND I'M GOING TO BE BACK AGAIN
TOMORROW.
BUT I'M GOING TO GO TO
WASHINGTON AND I'M GOING TO
RAISE THIS ISSUE, AND I THINK
IT'S TIME FOR THE CONVERSATION
TO BE RENEWED.
FOR THE DIALOGUE TO BEGIN AGAIN,
AND FOR THE SENATE TO CONSIDER
WHETHER THAT IS NECESSARY.
>> LET'S BRING IN OUR WHITE
HOUSE CORRESPONDENT BRIANN
BRIANNA KEILAR.
WHAT DO YOU SEE?
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL BE
HEADED TO NEWTOWN TO SPEAK AT AN
INTERFAITH VIGIL.
HE WILL BE OFFERING HIS
CONDOLENCES, NO DOUBT STRIKING A
TONE OF UNIYUAN BUT NOT TALKING
ABOUT WHAT HE SEES AS THE
SOLUTIONS TO AVERT SOMETHING
LIKE THIS.
THE WHITE HOUSE FEELS THAT THEY
DON'T WANT TO GET INTO SPECIFICS
ABOUT POLICIES THEY MIGHT PURSUE
IN THE WAKE OF THIS TRAGEDY.
THEY'RE AFRAID THAT IT WOULD BE
COUNTERPRODUCTIVE, THAT IT WOULD
BE INAPPROPRIATE CONSIDERING
THIS TRAGEDY JUST HAPPENED.
BUT THE SENSE THAT I GOTTEN,
WOLF, IS WHAT PRESIDENT OBAMA
SAID YESTERDAY SHOULD BE SEEN
VERY MUCH AS A PLEDGE TO DO
SOMETHING MORE THAN JUST TALK
ABOUT THIS PROBLEM.
AND FOR RIGHT NOW, GUN RIGHTS
ADVOCATES ARE BEING VERY QUIET.
THEY ARE BASICALLY SAYING NO
COMMENT.
BUT GUN CONTROL ADVOCATES ARE
SAYING THEY WANT MORE THAN A
VAGUE PLEDGE.
JUST HOURS AFTER THE CONNECTICUT
SHOOTING A PROMISE FROM
PRESIDENT OBAMA TO TACKLE GUN
VIOLENCE.
>> WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO COME
TOGETHER AND TAKE MEANINGFUL
ACTION TO BE PREVENT MORE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS, REGARDLESS
OF THE POLITICS.
>> BUT WHAT EXACTLY DOES HE MEAN
BY MEANINGFUL ACTION?
KRIT IGS OF THE PRESIDENT'S
RECORD ON THE ISSUE ARE PUSHING
FOR PROPOSALS.
CALLING FOR MEANINGFUL ACTION IS
NOT ENOUGH.
WE NEED IMMEDIATE ACTION.
WE HAVE HEARD ALL OF THE
RHETORIC BEFORE.
WHAT WE NEED IS LEADERSHIP,
WHICH WE HAVEN'T GOTTEN FROM THE
WHITE HOUSE OR THE CONGRESS.
AS PRESIDENT OBAMA RAN FOR
PRESIDENT IN 2008, OBAMA
SUPPORTED REINSTATING A BAN ON
ASSAULT WEAPONS.
>> DON'T TELL ME WE CAN'T UPHOLD
THE SECOND AMENDMENT WHILE
KEEPING AK-47s OUT OF THE HANDS
OF CRIMINALS.
>> Reporter: ONCE ELECTED HE DID
NOT MAKE GOOD ON HIS CAMPAIGN
PLEDGE.
THE BRADY CAMPAIGN TO PREVENT
GUN VIOLENCE GAVE THE PRESIDENT
ACROSS THE BOARD F'S ON ITS
REPORT CARD.
>> THE SENATE WILL COME TO ORDER
ORDER.
>> Reporter: A MAJOR OBSTACLE
FOR THE PRESIDENT -- CONGRESS,
WHERE THERE'S BEEN LITTLE
APPETITE TO TOUCH THE ISSUE.
MULTIPLE BILLS HAVE BEEN
INTRODUCED.
NOT A SINGLE ONE HAS MADE IT TO
THE FLOOR FOR A VOTE.
THOSE INVOLVED IN THE DEBATE
OVER GUNS SAYS THE PRESIDENT HAS
A NUMBER OF OPTIONS.
REINSTATING SOME FORT OF THE
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN THAT EXPIRED
IN 1994, BANNING HIGH-COUNT
MAGAZINES OR IMPROVING THE
REPORTING OF PEOPLE WITH MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES TO MAKE SURE THEY
ARE DISQUALIFIED FROM PURCHASING
FIREARMS.
POLLS SHOW AMERICANS HAVE BECOME
ACCUSTOMED TO DAILY REPORTS OF
GUN DEATHS.
FRIDAY MORNING A SHOOTER KILLED
A MEMORY M-- MEMPHIS POLICE
OFFICER WHO WAS A MOTHER OF
FOUR.
FRIDAY NIGHT, A MAN SHOT A WOMAN
AT A LAS VEGAS HOTEL BEFORE
KILLING HIMSELF.
EARLY SATURDAY MORNING IN
BIRMINGHAM, ALABAMA, POLICE
KILLED A GUNMAN INSIDE A
HOSPITAL WHERE THREE PEOPLE WERE
HURT.
BUT NEW YORK CONGRESSWOMAN
CAROLYN McCARTHY WHOSE HUSBAND
DIED AND SON WAS INJURED WHEN A
SHOOTER OPEN FIRED ON A LONG
ISLAND TRAIN IN 1993 SAYS THE
CONNECTICUT SHOOTING MAY BE WHAT
FORCES PRESIDENT OBAMA AND
CONGRESS TO FINALLY ADDRESS THE
PROBLEM.
>> LET'S FACE IT, WE NEED TO
HAVE THE PRESIDENT AS THE BULLY
PULL LIT ON TRYING TO GET
SOMETHING DONE.
THIS TIME, WHICH I SAW WAS
DIFFERENT, THAT POLITICIANS THAT
USUALLY DON'T TALK ABOUT IT WERE
TALKING ABOUT IT.
SO THERE IS A DIFFERENCE THIS
TIME AROUND THERE IS A
DIFFERENCE, MAYBE THE PENDULUM
IS TURNING AND THE COUNTRY IS
READY TO GET SERIOUS ABOUT THIS
ISSUE.
>> WHITE HOUSE SPOKESMAN JAY
CARNEY SAID NOW IS THE TIME TO
HAVE SYMPATHY FOR FAMILIES.
MAKING IT CLEAR HE DOESN'T THINK
IT'S TIME TO ENGAGE IN A POLICY
DEBATE.
BUT TALKING TO CONGRESSWOMAN
McCARTHY TODAY, SHE SAID WHEN
SHE HEARD THAT, SHE SAID SHE WAS
UPSET AND CALLED UP THE WHITE
HOUSE AND SAID WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
THIS IS SOMETHING WE SHOULD HAVE
BEEN TALKING ABOUT YEARS AGO.
>> AND BRIANNA, I UNDERSTAND
WITH' EAR ALSO GETTING NEW WORD
ABOUT THE PRESIDENT AND HIS
DECISION, AS FAR AS THE NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE IS CONCERNED.
>> THAT'S RIGHT, WOLF.
WE'RE JUST FINDING OUT THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS DECIDED ON
SENATOR JOHN KERRY TO REPLACE
HILLARY CLINTON AS THE SECRETARY
OF STATE.
THIS IS COMING TO CNN FROM A
DEMOCRAT WHO SPOKE WITH KERRY.
AND THAT SAME SOURCE SAYS THAT
THIS ANNOUNCEMENT COULD BE MADE
FORMAL AS EARLY AS NEXT WEEK.
AS YOU KNOW, WOLF, SORT OF THE
WAY WAS PAVED HERE FOR THIS TO
HAPPEN WHEN U.N. AMBASSADOR
SUSAN RICE WITHDREW HER NAME FOR
CONSIDERATION WITH THIS POST,
LEAVING SENATOR KERRY AS REALLY
THE ONLY OTHER NAME THAT WAS
REALLY BEING DISCUSSED.
>> BRIANNA KIELAR AT THE WHITE
HOUSE.
THANKS VERY MUCH.
OUR COVERAGE IS GOING TO
CONTINUE AT THE TOP OF THE HOUR
WITH ANDERSON COOPER.
YOU'LL BE BACK TOMORROW MORNING.
I'LL BE BACK LATER IN THE DAY AS
WELL.
WE'LL BE GEARING UP FOR THE
PRESIDENT WILL BE HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, TOMORROW
NIGHT.
GIVE US A FINAL THOUGHT BEFORE
WE GO.
>> I THINK ONE THING THAT YOU
AND I HAVE DEFINITELY SEEN AS WE
HAVE BEEN HERE TODAY, I'VE BEEN
TALKING WITH FAMILIES THAT HAVE
CHILDREN THAT WERE AT THE
SCHOOL.
I THINK IT'S CLEAR THAT THIS IS
A TOWN FOREVER CHANGED, BUT A
TOWN THAT WAS DEFINITELY COMING
TOGETHER TO GRIEVE AND HEAL
TOGETHER.
WOLF?
>> IT WILL TAKE A LONG TIME.
KATE, THANKS VERY MUCH.
THAT DOES IT.
I'M WOLF BLITZER HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
CNN'S COVERAGE OF THIS TRAGEDY
CONTINUES WITH A SPECIAL EDITION
OF "AC:360."
THAT'S NEXT.
THEY'VE BEEN COMMITTED
TO PUTTING CLIENTS FIRST.
HELPING GENERATIONS
THROUGH TOUGH TIMES.
GOOD TIMES.
NEVER TAKING A BAILOUT.
THERE WHEN YOU NEED THEM.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
OVER THE CENTURIES.
THE STRENGTH OF
A GLOBAL FINANCIAL LEADER.
THE HEART OF
A ONE-TO-ONE RELATIONSHIP.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
have led to an increase intands
TOclinical depression.RE.
Drug and alcohol abuse is up.
And those dealing with grief
don't have access to the
professional help they need.
When you see these issues, do
you want to walk away or
step up?
With a degree in the field of
Counseling or Psychology from
Capella University, you'll have
the knowledge to make
a difference in the lives of
others.
Let's get started at
CAPELLA.EDU