CTIONS
OR STOMACH AND INTESTINE
PROBLEMS,
SUCH AS BLEEDING AND ULCERS,
WHICH CAN OCCUR WITHOUT WARNING
AND MAY CAUSE DEATH.
PATIENTS ALSO TAKING ASPIRIN
AND THE ELDERLY
ARE AT INCREASED RISK FOR
STOMACH BLEEDING AND ULCERS.
DO NOT TAKE CELEBREX IF YOU'VE
HAD AN ASTHMA ATTACK, HIVES,
OR OTHER ALLERGIES TO ASPIRIN,
NSAIDS OR SULFONAMIDES.
GET HELP RIGHT AWAY IF YOU HAVE
SWELLING OF THE FACE OR THROAT,
OR TROUBLE BREATHING.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
YOUR MEDICAL HISTORY
AND FIND AN ARTHRITIS TREATMENT
FOR YOU.
VISIT CELEBREX.COM AND ASK
YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT CELEBREX.
FOR A BODY IN MOTION.
>>> HELLO EVERYONE.
I AM ASHLEIGH BANFIELD LIVE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THIS IS THE DAY THAT THE
STUDENTS GO BACK TO SCHOOL AFTER
ONE OF THE WORST SCHOOL
SHOOTINGS IN THE HISTORY OF THIS
COUNTRY.
THE SCHOOL DISTRICT IS SENDING
ITS CHILDREN BACK BUT THE SCHOOL
IN QUESTION, NO.
THE KIDS FROM SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY ARE NOT GOING BACK TO
CLASS TODAY.
THEY WON'T BE GOING BACK TO
CLASS FOR A WHILE.
THEY WILL GO BACK TO A SCHOOL IN
A NEIGHBORING TOWN IN MONROE.
IT IS BEING READIED FOR THOSE
CHILDREN AND THEY WILL RETURN.
AS OTHERS HAVE RETURNED ON A
TWO-HOUR DELAY TODAY.
ALL OF THIS AS THIS TOWN BURIES
YET ANOTHER OF ITS DEAD.
A 6-YEAR-OLD GIRL, JESSICA
REKOS.
HER FAMILY WILL LAY HER TO REST
TODAY.
AND JUST SO YOU KNOW A LITTLE
BIT MORE ABOUT THAT LITTLE
CHILD.
SHE LOVED HORSES.
SHE WANTED A COWBOY HAT AND
COWBOY BOOTS FOR CHRISTMAS.
HER PARENTS SPOKE WITH ABC NEWS
ABOUT THEIR LITTLE ANGEL.
>> SHE WAS A BALL OF FIRE.
SHE RULED THE ROOST.
>> OUR LITTLE CEO WE CALLED HER.
SHE WAS THE BOSS.
>> Reporter: AS THEY REMEMBER
THEIR CHILD THERE ARE SO MANY
FUNERALS THAT HAVE YET TO TAKE
PLACE IN THIS TOWN, NOT ONLY FOR
THE CHILDREN BUT THE TEACHERS,
AS WELL.
AT THIS TIME, THOUGH, THERE IS
THE BUSINESS OF GETTING THESE
CHILDREN BACK TO SOME KIND OF
NORMALCY AND FOR SO MANY PEOPLE
THAT MEANS SCHOOL.
SANDRA ENDO HAS BEEN COVERING
THAT ANGLE.
GIVE ME A BIT OF A BREAK DOWN ON
HOW THE SCHOOL DISTRICT GOT
THINGS UP TO SPEED SO QUICKLY
AND HOW THEY ARE PREPARED FOR
GETTING THE CHILDREN BACK INTO
SCHOOL SAFELY, SECURELY AND
MENTALLY.
>> Reporter: WELL, CERTAINLY A
BIG DAY FOR STUDENTS, PARENTS,
TEACHERS HERE IN NEWTOWN.
WE SAW BUSES ROLLING ALL MORNING
LONG.
AND BY THIS HOUR CLASSES HAVE
RESUMED.
AS YOU MENTIONED THERE WAS A
TWO-HOUR DELAY FOR ALL SCHOOLS.
BUT 5,400 SCHOOL STUDENTS IN
THIS DISTRICT HAVE RETURNED BACK
TO SCHOOL TODAY, THE FIRST TIME
SINCE FRIDAY'S TRAGEDY AND THEY
REALLY TOOK MONDAY TO PUSH THE
RESET BUTTON.
STUDENTS NEEDING A BREAK TRYING
TO ABSORB EVERYTHING THAT HAS
HAPPENED HERE IN THIS TOWN.
FOR STUDENTS AND TEACHERS AND
FACULTY THEY HAVE ALSO HAD A
CHANCE TO TALK TO GRIEVANCE
COUNSELORS AND TO FIGURE OUT HOW
BEST TO APPROACH RETURNING BACK
TO SCHOOL.
AND, OF COURSE, EXPERTS ARE
SAYING IT IS IMPORTANT FOR
STUDENTS TO GET BACK TO A
ROUTINE AND GET BACK TO A SENSE
OF NORMALCY.
THEY SAY THIS COULD BE THE FIRST
STEP TO HEALING.
AND WE KNOW THAT TRAINED
PROFESSIONALS, GUIDANCE
COUNSELORS, GRIEVANCE
COUNSELORS, POLICE OFFICERS WILL
ALL BE ON HAND AT THESE SCHOOLS.
PRINCIPALS HAVE TOLD PARENTS TO
MAKE SURE THEY TALK TO THEIR
CHILDREN BEFORE ENTERING A
CLASSROOM BECAUSE IT IS AN
UNCONTROLLED SETTING.
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT OTHER
STUDENTS MAY SAY.
YOU DON'T WANT YOUR CHILD TO
LEARN ABOUT THE TRAGEDY FROM
OTHER STUDENTS, AS WELL.
CLEARLY THEY ARE OPENING THE
LINES OF COMMUNICATION AND WE
KNOW THAT TEACHERS WILL BE
TALKING ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED HERE
IN NEWTOWN AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL TO THEIR
STUDENTS IN AN AGE APPROPRIATE
MANNER.
SO THEY REALLY THOUGHT OUT THE
PROCESS HERE AND THEY ARE HOPING
THAT A LOT OF THESE STUDENTS
COULD GET BACK TO A SENSE OF
ROUTINE AND A SENSE OF NORMALCY
IN ORDER TO HEAL.
>> AND SANDRA, I WANT TO MAKE
SURE THAT OUR VIEWERS ARE AWARE
OF THE PROTOCOL THAT HAS TAKEN
FORM ON ITS OWN HERE.
THESE ARE CHILDREN.
AND WE DON'T TAKE PICTURES OF
CHILDREN WITHOUT THEIR PARENTS'
PERMISSION.
WITH THE MAGNITUDE OF THE NUMBER
OF KIDS RETURNING TO SCHOOL,
PASSING BEHIND YOU THERE HAVE
BEEN SCHOOL BUSES.
I HAVE SEEN PARENTS WALKING
THEIR KIDS TO SCHOOL.
HOW HAS THE MEDIA RESPONDED TO
THE NEED FOR RESPECT OF THESE
PEOPLE'S PRIVACY DESPITE THE
FACT THAT NOTHING CAN BE REALLY
NORMAL?
>> Reporter: ABSOLUTELY.
WE ARE TAKING EVERY PRECAUTION
COVERING THIS STORY AND THIS
TREMENDOUS TRAGEDY THAT HAS
ROCKED THIS TOWN AND THE ENTIRE
NATION.
WE ARE NOT GOING NEARBY SCHOOLS.
WE ARE NOT SHOWING KIDS' FACES.
WE SEE THE PAIN AND AGONY IN SO
MANY PEOPLE'S FACES AS THEY COME
HERE TO THIS MAKE SHIFT MEMORIAL
IN THE MIDDLE OF TOWN TO PAY
RESPECTS AND CONDOLENCES TO THE
LIVES LOST IN THE TRAGEDY.
WE HAVE TALKED TO PARENTS AND
STUDENTS WHO ARE WILLING TO TALK
TO US.
I HAVE GOTTEN THE SENSE OF
ANXIETY OF RETURNING BACK TO
SCHOOL TODAY AND SOME PARENTS
AND STUDENTS SAY THEY ARE A
LITTLE NERVOUS AND SCARED BUT
CLEARLY THEY WANT TO GET BACK TO
SEEING THEIR FRIENDS AND HAVE
THAT SENSE OF COMMUNITY.
>> SANDRA ENDO REPORTING FOR US
LIVE IN FRONT OF ONE OF THE MANY
MAKE SHIFT MEMORIALS THAT HAVE
POPPED UP ALL AROUND TOWN.
I AM GOING TO TAKE YOU OVER TO
MONROE, THE NEIGHBORING TOWN.
IT IS ABOUT TO BECOME AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AGAIN.
I WILL GIVE YOU A LAY OF THE
LAND AS TO HOW THEY WILL
TRANSFORM THAT BUILDING TO MAKE
IT AS SIMILAR AS THEY CAN TO THE
ENVIRONMENT THAT THE LITTLE
CHILDREN LEFT BEHIND AT SANDY
HOOK.
THERE IS THIS PARALLEL BIT OF
BUSINESS AND THAT IS THE
CRIMINAL INVESTIGATION THAT IS
MASSIVE.
IT IS ON GOING.
AND MUCH OF IT FOCUSES ON THAT
YOUNG MAN WHO PERPETRATED THIS
HORRIBLE VIOLENCE.
SO MUCH OF IT THEY HOPE TO GET
FROM THE COMPUTER, THE FAMILY
COMPUTERS INSIDE THE HOME OF
ADAM LANZA AND HIS MOTHER.
SADLY, THOUGH, THOSE COMPUTERS
DON'T APPEAR TO BE IN VERY GOOD
SHAPE AND DEBORAH JOINS US FROM
THAT HOME.
GIVE ME A BIT OF WHAT
INVESTIGATORS FOUND WHEN THEY
WENT THROUGH THAT HOME?
>> Reporter: ALL OF THE
MYSTERIES OF WHAT WAS GOING ON
INSIDE OF ADAM LANZA'S MIND, THE
MYSTERY IS LOCKED INSIDE THIS
HOME.
THIS IS WHERE HE KILLED HIS
MOTHER, SHOT IN THE HEAD BEFORE
GOING ON HIS RAMPAGE.
WE CAN TELL YOU THAT
INVESTIGATORS WERE ABLE TO FIND
COMPUTERS OR AT LEAST ONE
COMPUTER.
BUT IT WAS SMASHED.
THEY ARE TRYING TO PIECE
TOGETHER THE SHARDS TO HOPEFULLY
SEE WHAT KIND OF E-MAILS HE WAS
SENDING AND WEBSITES HE WAS
GOING TO AND THE DIGITAL FOOT
PRINT THAT MAY ALLOW THEM TO
UNDERSTAND WHAT HE WAS THINKING
ABOUT.
WE HAVE A COUPLE OF PIECES OF
NEW INFORMATION.
FIRST OF ALL JUST TO SET THE
SCENE HERE, THIS HOME ON THIS
HILL, SCHOOL BUSES GOING PAST
THIS MORNING WITH CHILDREN WHO
ARE GOING BACK TO SCHOOL AND
CLEARLY THE ABSENCE OF SOME
CHILDREN WHO SHOULD HAVE BEEN ON
THOSE BUSES.
TWO CHILDREN WHO DIED IN THAT
MASSACRE ACTUALLY LIVE LESS THAN
HALF A MILE FROM THIS PARTICULAR
HOME.
SO THAT IS THE KIND OF COMMUNITY
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT.
WE ARE LEARNING THAT A FRIEND
WHO WAS DOING WORK INSIDE THE
HOME ABOUT EIGHT MONTHS AGO TOLD
ME HE NOTICED THERE WAS A GUN
LOCK BOX THAT ADAM LANZA KEPT IN
THE BASEMENT.
THAT IS WHERE IT IS BELIEVED
THAT SHE KEPT THE GUNS SHE
POSSESSED.
SHE LIKED SHOOTING, WAS SORT OF
A COUNTRY GIRL.
TO HAVE A LOCK BOX WITH THE GUNS
WE DON'T KNOWHETHER THEY WERE
INSIDE AT THE TIME.
NANCY INITIALLY TOOK HER SON TO
THE SHOOTING RANGES BECAUSE SHE
DIDN'T WANT TO LEAVE HIM ALONE
FOR LARGE PERIODS OF TIME.
THAT IS WHEN HE MAY HAVE BEGUN
TO BE INTERESTED IN THIS CONCEPT
OF SHOOTING, FIRING.
WE DO KNOW THAT ADAM LANZA WAS
TRYING TO TRY TO MAINSTREAM HER
SON.
IT WAS CLEAR THAT HE HAD
PROBLEMS.
A SCHOOL SECURITY OFFICER
APPOINTED SPECIFIC OFFICERS TO
KEEP AN EYE ON HIM.
THEY DIDN'T WANT HIM TO BECOME A
TARGET OF OTHER CHILDREN WITHIN
THE SCHOOL.
HE WAS SEEING A PSYCHOLOGIST
WHEN HE WAS A FRESHMAN.
THAT ALSO SCHOOL APPOINTED.
IN GOING THROUGH THE DIVORCE
DOCUMENT AND TRYING TO MAKE
SENSE OF ALL OF THIS WE FOUND
OTTHAT WHILE THE FATHER WAS
RESPONSIBLE FOR THE MEDICAL CARE
THE MOTHER WAS RESPONSIBLE FOR
ALL PSYCHIATRIC AND
PSYCHOLOGICAL EXPENSES AND
RESPONSIBLE FOR PRESCRIPTION
MEDICATIONS.
THEY ARE LOOKING AT ALL OF THIS
TO TRY TO FIND OUT WHAT KIND OF
MEDICATIONS HE WAS ON AND
WHETHER OR NOT HE MAY HAVE BEEN
GETTING THAT TREATMENT.
WE HAVE SEEN THIS OUTPOURING
THAT YOU TALK ABOUT THERE IN
NEWTOWN.
FOR THE FIRST TIME SOMEBODY CAME
AND LAID FLOWERS AT THE HOME OF
NANCY LANZA.
SHE WAS A WOMAN WHO WAS VERY
MUCH LIKED.
SHE WAS STRUGGLING BUT AT LEAST
TRYING TO DO THE RIGHT THING BY
HER SON, BY HERSELF AND BY HER
FAMILY.
>> I AM GLAD YOU SAID THAT
BECAUSE OFTEN TIMES IN THE
SADNESS THAT HAS ENVELOPED THIS
COMMUNITY THERE IS A LOT OF
FOCUS ON THOSE THAT DIED AT THE
SCHOOL AND TEACHERS AND CHILDREN
AND RIGHTFULLY SO BUT YOU HAVE
TO REMEMBER THAT SHE WAS A
MURDER VICTIM HERE SHOT IN HER
OWN BED.
THAT FAMILY IS GRIEVING, AS
WELL.
I AM SURE THAT ADAM LANZA'S
FATHER IS GOING THROUGH HIS OWN
PERSONAL HELL AS TWO OF HIS
FAMILY MEMBERS ARE NOW DEAD.
AND YOU SHOULD ALSO KNOW THAT
THE ATF HAS TOLD CNN THAT ADAM
LANZA HAS AATTENDED SEVERAL
DIFFERENT GUN RANGES WITH HIS
MOTHER.
HE HAD TAKEN UP SHOOTING AS A
HOBBY.
[ Male Announcer ]
RESEARCH SUGGESTS CELL HEALTH
PLAYS A KEY ROLE
THROUGHOUT OUR LIVES.
One A Day Men's 50+
IS A COMPLETE MULTIVITAMIN
DESIGNED FOR MEN'S HEALTH
CONCERNS AS WE AGE.
IT HAS 7 ANTIOXIDANTS
TO SUPPORT CELL HEALTH.
One A Day Men's 50+.
>>> JUST THE OVERWHELMING
DETAILS OF WHAT TRANSPIRED IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT HAS GRIPPED
THIS NATION IN A WAY THAT OTHER
HORRIBLE TRAGEDIES PERHAPS HAS
NOT.
THERE WERE 20 CHILDREN
SLAUGHTERED AT POINT BLANK RANGE
AND SIX GROWNUPS AT THAT SCHOOL
WHO WERE SLAUGHTERED AT POINT
BLANK RANGE WITH AN ASSAULT
WEAPON THAT MANY PEOPLE FEEL
SHOULD NOT BE LEGAL AND OTHER
PEOPLE FEEL SHOULD BE A FREEDOM.
THERE MAY BE A SLIGHT SHIFT OF
ATTITUDE.
THERE ARE SOME POLLING NUMBERS
THAT ARE COMING OUT LATELY.
THE LATEST ONE FROM CBS NEWS
SHOWING THE MAJORITY OF
AMERICANS SHIFTED THEIR
OPINIONS.
57% THINK GUN LAWS SHOULD BE
MORE STRICT.
30% SAYING IT SHOULD BE KEPT THE
SAME.
SOME PROMINENT DEMOCRATIC
LAWMAKERS WHO ARE NRA SUPPORTERS
HAVE SHIFTED THEIR OPINIONS, AS
WELL.
AND NOW MANY ARE SAYING THAT IT
IS TIME TO BRING BACK THE BAN ON
ASSAULT WEAPONS.
DEMOCRATIC CONGRESS WOMAN ELECT
ELIZABETH SETI WILL BE SWORN IN.
CLEARLY YOU JUST SAW THE NUMBERS
THAT HAVE COME OUT.
THOSE ARE VERY RECENT.
AND THERE IS THIS NOTION THAT
THERE IS A GROUND SWELL, A
SHIFT.
I DON'T KNOW THAT THAT IS TRUE
YET.
THESE ARE NUMBERS JUST
IMMEDIATELY FOLLOWING A TRAGIC
INCIDENT THAT HAS BEEN
BLANKETING THE NEWS.
HOW ARE LAWMAKERS RESPONDING?
NOT TO SUGGEST YOU ARE AT
CAPITOL HILL YET.
WHAT IS YOUR SENSE OF WHAT IS
HAPPENING DOWN THERE?
>> WHAT I AM HEARING FROM
COLLEAGUES AROUND THE COUNTRY
AND FROM FRIENDS AROUND THE
COUNTRY AND FROM PARENTS RIGHT
HERE IN NEWTOWN THAT SOMETHING
HAS TO BE DONE.
AND I DO THINK THERE ARE TIPPING
POINTS.
I AM A MOTHER OF THREE.
I HAVE BEEN A ROOM PARENT IN THE
FIRST GRADE CLASSROOM.
AND I THINK THE IMAGE OF THESE
YOUNG CHILDREN, OF SIX YEAR OLDS
A WEEK BEFORE THE HOLIDAYS IS SO
HEARTBREAKING THAT IT IS
BREAKING THROUGH THE SENSE WE
CAN'T DO ANYTHING.
THAT IS A QUESTION OF POLITICAL
WILL.
>> IT MAY BE BREAKING THROUGH
THE SENSE FOR SOME.
THERE ARE AT LEAST TWO
DEMOCRATIC LAWMAKERS VERY
SUPPORTIVE OF THE NRA WHO ARE
SHIFTING THEIR FOCUS AND THEIR
FEELING.
DO YOU SENSE THAT THAT IS GOING
TO BE THE SAME FOR MOST
REPUBLICAN LAWMAKERS WHO ALMOST
TO THE LETTER OF THE D AND THE R
DON'T SUPPORT STRICTER GUN
CONTROL MEASURES.
DO YOU SEE THAT THAT IS GOING TO
PLEAD TO THE REPUBLICAN SIDE OF
THE AISLE?
>> I THINK THERE WILL BE A
NATIONAL CONVERSATION WHICH I
WANT TO BE A PART OF BECAUSE
PART OF THE HEALING PROCESS IS
MOVING FORWARD IN A WAY TO
PREVENT ANY OTHER COMMUNITY TO
EXPERIENCE WHAT HAS HAPPENED TO
THIS COMMUNITY HERE WHICH IS A
TREASURED COMMUNITY.
20 YOUNG INNOCENT CHILDREN, FOUR
TEACHERS AND A SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST WHO LAID DOWN THEIR
LIVES TO PROTECT THEIR STUDENTS.
WE SHOULD NOT BE HAVING THIS IN
OUR CLASSROOMS.
>> THERE IS A NATIONAL
CONVERSATION.
WE ARE HAVING IT RIGHT NOW.
IT HAS BEEN GOING ON FOR SEVERAL
DAYS.
HOW CANTANKEROUS THAT
CONVERSATION IS GOING TO BECOME?
WE HAVE SOME SUGGEST ISSING
TEACHERS NEED TO BE ARMED.
THERE IS A DIGGING IN OF
CONVICTIONS.
ARE THINGS GOING TO CHANGE?
WILL THERE BE A CHANGE?
IS THIS HORROR THAT WAS VISITED
UPON YOUR COMMUNITY GOING TO
MAKE A DIFFERENCE IN TERMS OF
WHO FALLS ON WHAT SIDE OF THE
DEBATE OR WILL PEOPLE BECOME
MORE ENTRENCHED?
>> I CERTAINLY HOPE THIS WILL BE
AN OPPORTUNITY TO MOVE FORWARD
POSITIVELY WITH LAWS THAT WORK
AND A CONVERSATION OF CULTURAL
VIOLENCE IN THE COUNTRY AND A
REAL ADDRESS OF MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES.
WE ARE HEARING A RECOGNITION
THAT THIS IS AN ISSUE THAT WE
HAVE NOT DEALT WITH VERY WELL AS
A COUNTRY AND WE NEED TO PROTECT
THOSE CHILDREN AND TO PROTECT
EVERYONE'S CHILDREN.
I AM HOPEFUL.
I WOULDN'T HAVE RUN FOR CONGRESS
IF I WEREN'T HOPEFUL THAT WE
COULD SOLVE THESE PROBLEMS AND
FIND COMMON GROUND AND WE WILL
NEED TO FORGE THAT COMMON GROUND
WITH THE SUPPORT OF THE PUBLIC.
>> IT WILL BE INTERESTING TO SEE
WHAT HAPPENS IN THE NEW SESSION.
GOOD LUCK TO YOU AS YOU HEAD
INTO YOUR NEW JOB IN THE NEW
YEAR.
I AM SO SORRY WE MET UNDER THESE
CIRCUMSTANCES.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> AS THE CONGRESS WOMAN SPEAKS
TO ME THIS IS HER DISTRICT.
BUSINESSES ARE TAKING ACTION, AS
WELL.
WE LEARNED THAT DICK'S SPORTING
GOODS IS SUSPENDING THE SALES OF
MODERN SPORTING RIFLES IN ALL
THE CHAINS.
THEY ARE NOT DISPLAYING THE GUNS
IN THE COMMUNITY NEAR HERE.
THE PRIVATE EQUITY FIRM IS
SELLING OFF THE MAKER OF THE
BUSHMASTER RIFLE THAT WAS USED
IN THE SHOOTING THAT TOOK SO
MANY LIVES.
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
CONNECTING
TO THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
♪
How advanced is the
new Ford Fusion?
Well...it has outstanding
performance and handling...
...and it offers a plug-in
hybrid
that gets a projected 100 MPGe.
Of course, there's still
one thing it can't do.
Introducing the entirely
new Ford Fusion.
It's an entirely new idea of
what a car can be.
>>> ONE OF THE FIRST THINGS YOU
WILL NOTICE AS YOU DRIVE INTO
THIS BEAUTIFUL TOWN OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT IS SOME OF THE OLD
BUILDINGS AND THE LOVELY GENTLY
ROLLING HILLSIDE AND THEN THIS
EXTRAORDINARY TRAFFIC.
THE SCHOOL BUSES ARE ROLLING
ONCE AGAIN AS THESE KIDS GET
READY TO HEAD BACK TO SCHOOL.
IT IS NOT NORMALLY LIKE THIS.
THE TRAFFIC IS COMPROMISED OF
PEOPLE FROM SURROUNDING
COUNTIES, CONTRACTORS WHO ARE
COMING IN TO HELP WITH THIS
EMERGENCY, MAYBE REBUILDING IN
SOME OF THE SCHOOLS, ETC.
AND THEN ALSO AN ENORMOUS NUMBER
OF MEDIA.
ANOTHER THING YOU NOTICE AS YOU
COME INTO TOWN RIGHT AWAY ON THE
LEFT-HAND SIDE IS THIS MAKE
SHIFT MEMORIAL THAT SPRUNG UP
SEVERAL DAYS AGO AND IS GROWING
EXPONENTIALLY.
PEOPLE BRINGING TEDDY BEARS AND
CANDLES AND ARTWORK AND ORIGAMI
AND FLOWERS.
YOU SEE A LOT OF PEOPLE WITH
TEARS AS THEY DROP OFF WHAT THEY
BROUGHT.
OBVIOUSLY SOME OF THE TRAFFIC
WITH PEOPLE FROM THE SURROUNDING
COMMUNITIES.
THE NEXT THING YOU NOTICE IS
THIS, ALL OF THIS MEDIA.
PEOPLE HAVE COME FROM ALL OVER
THE WORLD TO COVER THIS STORY.
AND THEY ARE SET UP RIGHT IN THE
TOWN SQUARE RIGHT IN THE CENTER
OF TOWN, A PLACE THAT IS NOT
USED TO SEEING SATELLITE TRUCKS
AND THIS KIND OF MEDIA
ATTENTION.
BOY, ARE THEY GETTING USED TO IT
NOW.
ANOTHER THING THAT YOU WILL FIND
AMIDST ALL THE TRAFFIC, TAKE A
LOOK UP HERE.
POLICE AND ORANGE CONES AND ROAD
CLOSED SIGNS.
THAT IS THE ROADT THAT LEADS UP
TO THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
THEY ARE OBVIOUSLY LIMITING MOST
OF THE TRAFFIC, NOT ALLOWED TO
GO UP THERE AT THIS TIME.
THAT IS THE OTHER AREA WHERE
THERE IS A MASSIVE, MASSIVE
MEMORIAL.
I SHOWED THAT TO YOU YESTERDAY.
ONE OF THE THINGS THAT WE DO
HEAR FROM PEOPLE WHILE EVERYBODY
AROUND THE COUNTRY AND AROUND
THE WORLD WANTS TO SHARE AND
WANTS TO KNOW AND WANTS TO BE A
PART OF THIS GRIEVING AND THEY
ARE DOING THAT THROUGH US AND
THE WINDOW WE PROVIDE, THE
PEOPLE WHO LIVE HERE REALLY
WOULD LIKE US TO LEAVE.
THEY WANT TO RETURN TO SOME KIND
OF NORMALCY.
WHEN WE DO GO AND WHEN WE DO
LEAVE THIS TOWN AND WHEN OUR
WORLD CONTINUES, WE LEAVE ALL OF
THESE PEOPLE WITH A BRAND NEW
NORMAL AND SOMETHING THEY ARE
GOING TO HAVE TO FIGURE OUT FOR
THEMSELVES WHAT THEIR NEW NORMAL
IS GOING TO BE LIKE.
I REMEMBER SO WELL AFTER
SEPTEMBER 11th, THE TERM THE NEW
NORMAL BECAME SO COMMON PLACE.
AND IT SEEMS TO BE ONE OF THE
THINGS THAT THESE PEOPLE HERE
ARE GOING TO HAVE TO ADOPT.
THE NOTION THAT THEY WILL HAVE A
NEW NORMAL.
BUT THEY ARE GOING TO NEED A LOT
OF HELP TO GET THERE.
AND THERE ARE A LOT OF PEOPLE
WHO WILL HELP THEM.
WENDY DAVIDSON IS THE GRIEF
COUNSELOR FROM THIS COMMUNITY.
SHE IS A LICENSED CERTIFIED
GRIEF COUNSELOR.
HAVE YOU HAD A CHANCE TO SPEAK
WITH ANY FAMILIES?
HAS ANYONE REACHED OUT TO YOU
YET?
I KNOW IT IS EARLY IN THIS
PROCESS.
>> NO.
NOT YET.
THE PEOPLE WHO HAVE REACHED OUT
TO ME ARE EITHER SOME OF THE
SCHOOL STAFF OR FAMILIES WHOSE
CHILDREN WERE FRIENDS WITH SOME
OF THE CHILDREN.
>> THIS IS A TOWN OF 27,000
PEOPLE.
I CANNOT IMAGINE THE AMOUNT OF
WORK THAT LIES AHEAD IN YOUR
FIELD.
HOW ARE YOU GOING TO HANDLE THE
AMOUNT OF COUNSELING THAT IS
NEEDED?
HOW MANY OUTSIDE COUNSELORS ARE
GOING TO HAVE TO COME HERE?
>> I THINK WE WILL PROBABLY
PROVIDE A LOT OF GROUP SERVICES.
I THINK WHAT WE DO -- I ALREADY
RUN A BEREAVEMENT GROUP FOR
FAMILIES WHO HAVE LOST CHILDREN.
WE WILL CONTINUE TO DO THAT.
WE WILL PROBABLY ADAPT IT MORE
SPECIFICALLY TO THOSE WHO MAY
NEED IT RIGHT AWAY.
A LOT OF PEOPLE DON'T NEED GRIEF
COUNSELING RIGHT AWAY.
THEY NEED TO HAVE A CHANCE TO
JUST SORT OF SETTLE DOWN AND LET
REALITY SET IN.
AFTER EVERYBODY LEAVES THERE IS
GOING TO BE A HUGE CRASH.
>> THAT IS WHAT I JUST MENTIONED
WHEN I WAS WALKING THROUGH TOWN.
A LOT OF PEOPLE WANT US TO GO.
I UNDERSTAND THAT.
A LOT OF PEOPLE WATCHING WANT TO
BE HERE AND THEY CAN ONLY BE
HERE THROUGH THE MEDIA SO WE
FEEL WE HAVE A RESPONSIBILITY.
WE WANT TO LEAVE AND WANT TO LET
PEOPLE GET BACK TO NORMAL.
WHEN WE LEAVE I THINK THERE WILL
BE AN ENORMOUS VACUUM AND QUIET
THUD OF SILENCE AND PAIN.
THE PEOPLE OF COLUMBINE SAID
THEY WANTED TO MOVE AWAY.
THEY SAID THEY WANTED TO LEAVE
LITTLETON, COLORADO.
AND IN THE END ULTIMATELY ALL
STAYED TOGETHER AND FOUND SO
MUCH COMFORT AND SUPPORT IN
BEING A GROUP.
IS THERE SOMETHING TO THAT IN
KNOWING THAT THERE ARE OTHER
PEOPLE AROUND YOU WHO KNOW
EXACTLY WHAT YOU ARE GOING
THROUGH?
>> DEFINITELY.
EVERYBODY'S FIRST REACTION IS TO
RETURN HOME TO ANOTHER HOME.
>> SOME OTHER HOME.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
EVEN AFTER 9/11 I DID A LOT OF
STRESS DEBRIEFING.
PEOPLE WANTED TO GO BACK TO
THEIR NATIVE COUNTRIES WHERE
HERE INITIALLY PEOPLE MAY WANT
TO LEAVE BUT I THINK IT WILL BE
VERY HELPFUL TO BAND TOGETHER.
>> I HAVE TO ASK YOU FOR THOSE
WHO SURVIVED AND FOR THOSE
PEOPLE IN TOWN WHO KNOW WHEN
THEY GO TO THE BANK AND CAFE AND
WALK THROUGH TOWN THEY ARE GOING
TO EVERY DAY ENCOUNTER SOMEONE
WHO LOST SOMEONE.
HOW ARE THEY SUPPOSED TO REACT?
WHAT ARE THEY SUPPOSED TO DO
WHEN THEY SEE THESE VICTIMS AND
FAMILY MEMBERS IN THE YEARS TO
COME?
>> ALL THEY NEED TO DO IS TO SAY
I AM HERE AND I AM THINKING OF
YOU.
NOTHING ELSE.
>> BUT TO BRING IT UP.
>> BRING IT UP JUST TO SAY I AM
HERE.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO ASK ANY
PERSONAL QUESTIONS OR HOW YOU
ARE DOING.
WHAT THEY SHOW AND WHAT THEY
TELL YOU IS NOT REALLY WHAT IS
GOING ON.
IT IS A BROKEN HEART.
I THINK WHAT THEY WILL DO IS SAY
I AM HERE AND I AM THINKING
ABOUT YOU.
THAT IS IT.
>> I AM SO SORRY FOR WHAT YOUR
TOWN IS GOING THROUGH AND WILL
CONTINUE TO GO THROUGH.
I WISH YOWL THE BEST OF LUCK IN
MANAGING THIS CRISIS.
>> I THINK WE WILL GROW AND HEAL
AS WE ARE GROWING.
>> THANK YOU FOR BEING HERE
TODAY AND FOR HELPING US TO SORT
THROUGH HOW THIS IS GOING TO
TRANSPIRE.
THERE IS A LOT THAT NEEDS TO BE
DONE.
IF YOU WANT INFORMATION ON HOW
YOU CAN PAY TRIBUTE FOR THE
VICTIMS OF THE NEWTOWN SHOOTING
WE INVITE YOU TO GO TO
CNN.COM/IMPACT.
THERE ARE PLENTY OF SUGGESTIONS
ON WHAT YOU CAN DO TO FEEL LIKE
YOU ARE INVOLVED.
TAKE TYLENOL OR TAKE ALEVE,
THE #1 RECOMMENDED PAIN
RELIEVER BY ORTHOPEDIC DOCTORS.
JUST TWO ALEVE
CAN KEEP PAIN AWAY ALL DAY.
BACK TO THE NEWS.
>>> SOME BUSINESS OUT OF
WASHINGTON TO BRING YOUR WAY.
THERE HAS BEEN SOME MOVEMENT.
I SAY SOME MOVEMENT ON THE PLANS
TO AVOID THE FISCAL CLIFF.
AND WHEN I SAY SOME MOVEMENT IT
MEANS PLAN B BECAUSE REPUBLICANS
ARE APPARENTLY READYING
SOMETHING TO CONSIDER PLAN B TO
TRY TO AVOID GOING OFF THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
WE ARE COUNTING DOWN TWO WEEKS
UNTIL THE DEADLINE.
THE DEAL HAS TO BE MADE BEFORE
THEN.
THE REPUBLICANS ARE SAYING THAT
A COUNTEROFFER CAME THEIR WAY
FROM PRESIDENT OBAMA ON TAXES
AND SPENDING AS QUOTE NOT THERE
YET.
DANA BASH JOINS ME LIVE FROM
CAPITOL HILL.
I KNOW THAT THE SPEAKER OF THE
HOUSE SPOKE JUST LAST HOUR ABOUT
HIS CONCERNS AND THOUGHTS MOVING
FORWARD.
ARE WE GETTING ANYTHING OTHER
THAN RHETORIC AND PLATITUDES?
ARE WE FINDING FURTHER MOVEMENT
AHEAD?
>> Reporter: WE ARE DEFINITELY
GETTING A LOT OF RHETORIC AND
PLATITUDES.
HIGH STAKES POSITIONING AND
TACTICAL POSITIONING RIGHT NOW
AS WE GET CLOSER TO THAT
DEADLINE.
BUT BIG PICTURE OF WHAT IS GOING
ON IS THAT THE HOUSE SPEAKER
WENT INTO A MEETING AND
ANNOUNCED HE WAS GOING TO MOVE
FORWARD TO PLAN B.
WHAT IS PLAN B?
HE FEELS THAT THE TALKS HE HAS
HAD WITH THE PRESIDENT HAVE
STALLED.
HE IS NOT GETTING ENOUGH OF WHAT
HE WANTS IN TERMS OF SPENDING
CUTS AND TOO MUCH WHEN IT COMES
TO TAX REVENUE.
PLAN B WOULD BE TO MAKE SURE
EVERYBODY'S TAXES DON'T GO UP.
IT WOULD BE LEGISLATION TO KEEP
TAXES WHERE THEY ARE FOR PEOPLE
MAKING $1 MILLION AND LESS.
LISTEN TO WHAT HE TOLD REPORTERS
AFTERWARDS.
>> AT THE SAME TIME WE WILL
CONTINUE TO TALK WITH THE
PRESIDENT WE ARE GOING TO ALSO
MOVE PLAN B.
I THINK WE ALL KNOW THAT EVERY
INCOME TAX FILER IN AMERICA IS
GOING TO PAY HIGHER RATES COME
JANUARY 1 UNLESS CONGRESS ACTS.
SO I BELIEVE IT IS IMPORTANT
THAT WE PROTECT AS MANY AMERICAN
TAXPAYERS AS WE CAN.
AND OUR PLAN B WOULD PROTECT
AMERICAN TAXPAYERS WHO MAKE $1
MILLION OR LESS AND HAVE ALL OF
THEIR CURRENT RATES EXTENDED.
>> Reporter: AS WE WERE TALKING,
THE WHITE HOUSE OFFICIALLY
RELEASED THE STATEMENT REJECTING
THE SO-CALLED PLAN B LEGISLATION
AND THAT IS NOT A SURPRISE
BECAUSE IT IS IN KEEPING WITH
WHAT WE HAVE HEARD FROM
DEMOCRATS.
SENIOR DEMOCRATS WHO LAUGHED
THIS OFF AS A JOKE.
ONE SENIOR DEMOCRAT SAID THIS IS
A PUNCH LINE, NOT A COMPROMISE.
BECAUSE THEY BELIEVE THAT THE
PRESIDENT IN RECENT DAYS HAS
MOVED MORE TOWARDS THE SPEAKER
THAN EVEN MANY IN THE
PRESIDENT'S OWN PARTY WANT HIM
TO AND THAT THE SPEAKER SIMPLY
CAN'T DEAL WITH THE PRESSURE
THAT HE IS GETTING FROM FELLOW
REPUBLICANS.
THERE ARE CERTAINLY A LOT OF
ISSUES GOING ON HERE BUT RIGHT
NOW IT LOOKS LIKE THE
REPUBLICANS ARE GOING TO PUSH
FORWARD ON TAKING THIS VOTE
PROBABLY ON THURSDAY AND BY ALL
ACCOUNTS IT DOES NOT LOOK LIKE
IT WILL GET THE VOTES TO PASS.
>> AS YOU WERE SPEAKING ACTUALLY
I JUST GOT THIS STATEMENT HERE.
LET ME READ FOR OUR AUDIENCE IF
I CAN.
THE PRESIDENT HAS PUT A BALANCED
REASONABLE PROPOSAL ON THE TABLE
THAT ACHIEVES SIGNIFICANT
DEFICIT REDUCTION AND REFLECTS
REAL COMPROMISE BY MEETING THE
REPUBLICANS HALF WAY ON REVENUE
AND MORE THAN HALF WAY ON
SPENDING FROM WHERE EACH SIDE
STARTED.
THE PARAMETERS OF THE DEAL ARE
CLEAR AND THE PRESIDENT IS
WILLING TO CONTINUE TO WORK WITH
REPUBLICANS TO REACH A
BIPARTISAN SOLUTION THAT AVERTS
THE FISCAL CLIFF, PROTECTS THE
MIDDLE CLASS AND PUTS OUR NATION
ON A FISCALLY SUSTAINABLE PATH
BUT HE IS NOT WILLING TO ACCEPT
A DEAL THAT DOESN'T ASK ENOUGH
OF THE VERY WEALTHIEST IN TAXES
AND INSTEAD SHIFTATHIZE BURDEN
TO THE MIDDLE CLASS.
THE PLAN B APPROACH DOESN'T MEET
THIS TEST BECAUSE IT CAN'T PASS
THE SENATE AND WILL NOT PROTECT
THE MIDDLE CLASS FAMILIES AND
DOES LITTLE TO ADDRESS OUR
FISCAL CHALLENGES WITH ZERO
SPENDING CUTS.
THE PRESIDENT IS HOPEFUL TO
REACH A SOLUTION SO WE DON'T
MISS THE OPPORTUNITY IN FRONT OF
US TODAY.
SO THERE IS THAT.
I DON'T KNOW THAT YOU CAN CALL
THAT PLATITUDES AND RHETORIC.
IT SOUNDS LIKE A LOT OF THE
SAME.
CAN I GET QUICK REACTION FROM
YOU ON THE STATEMENT?
>> Reporter: I THINK IT WOULD
SERVE THE VIEWERS WELL TO SHOW
THE GIST OF WHERE THE PRESIDENT
WAS LAST NIGHT WHEN HE MET WITH
THE HOUSE SPEAKER ON THE BIG
PICTURE NEGOTIATIONS, WHAT HE
OFFERED BECAUSE HE DID OFFER
SOME THINGS THAT HE BEFORE VOWED
HE NEVER WOULD.
HE IS MOVING TOWARDS THE SPEAKER
IN SOME WAYS.
ON THE TAX RATES FOR THE
WEALTHIEST AMERICANS PRESIDENT
CAMPAIGNED FOR FIVE YEARS SAYING
THEY WOULD GO UP FOR EVERYONE
MAKING $250,000 OR MORE.
LAST NIGHT HE OFFERED TO MOVE
THAT LEVEL UP TO $400,000.
HE ALSO OFFERED WHAT THE WHITE
HOUSE CALLS $1.2 TRILLION IN
SPENDING CUTS.
THE REPUBLICANS QUIBBLED WITH
THAT.
THEY SAID THE MATH DOESN'T ADD
UP.
REGARDLESS THAT IS A LOT MORE IN
SPENDING CUTS THAN THEY WOULD
HAVE AGREED TO AND THAT IS
COMING THE SPEAKER'S WAY.
AND THE OTHER THING THAT THE
PRESIDENT OFFERED WAS TO EXTEND
THE DEBT LIMIT SO THAT THAT IS
NOT A FIGHT THAT DRAWS EVERYBODY
INTO THE SAME POSITION WE ARE IN
NOW.
THAT IS SORT OF PART OF WHERE
THE NEGOTIATIONS ARE GOING.
AS YOU HEARD FROM THE SOUND BYTE
HE IS ARGUING HE SAID MORE
IMPORTANTLY TO HIS FELLOW
REPUBLICANS IN PRIVATE THIS
MORNING THAT THAT SIMPLY IS NOT
ENOUGH WHEN IT COMES TO
SPENDING.
LET ME GIVE YOU A REALITY CHECK
HERE.
SO MUCH OF THIS IS POSTURING AND
IS A NEGOTIATED TACTIC SAYING TO
THE PRESIDENT I NEED YOU TO COME
FURTHER MY WAY OR ELSE WE ARE
GOING TO HAVE THIS VOTE.
HE ALSO PROBABLY NEEDS TO DO
THAT FOR HIS OWN PEOPLE TO SHOW
THAT THE FALL BACK PLAN DOESN'T
HAVE THE VOTES TO PASS.
>> DANA BASH LIVE FOR US ON
CAPITOL HILL.
A LOT OF BREAKING NEWS COMING
OUR WAY AT THAT TIME.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
LET'S HOPE THE SENATE LEADERS
HAVE BEEN A ABLE TO CALL THEIR
FAMILIES BECAUSE THEY ARE
WARNING LAWMAKERS THAT THEY
COULD BE WORKING THROUGH TO
CHRISTMAS AND COME BACK THE NEXT
DAY IN ORDER TO TRY TO AVERT
THIS PROBLEM.
WE ARE BACK RIGHT AFTER THIS.
Y.
YOU KNOW HOW TO MIX BUSINESS...
WITH BUSINESS.
AND YOU...RENT FROM NATIONAL.
BECAUSE ONLY NATIONAL LETS YOU
CHOOSE ANY CAR IN THE AISLE.
AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE A FULL-SIZE
OR ABOVE.
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
I COULD GET USED TO THIS.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, YOU COULD BUSINESS PRO.
YES, YOU COULD.
GO NATIONAL. GO LIKE A PRO.
>>> IN THE STATE OF TEXAS WITH
OUR CONCEALED HAND GUN LICENSE
IF YOU GO THROUGH THE PROCESS
AND YOU HAVE BEEN DULY
BACKGROUNDED AND TRAINED AND YOU
ARE A CONCEALED HAND GUN
LICENSED CARRYING INDIVIDUAL YOU
SHOULD BE ABLE TO CARRY YOUR
HAND GUN ANYWHERE IN THIS STATE.
>> TEXAS GOVERNOR RICK PERRY
WEIGHING IN ON THE DEBATE OVER
GUN CONTROL AND WEIGHING IN IN A
WAY THAT OTHERS AREN'T AT THIS
TIME SUGGESTING THAT YOU SHOULD
BE ABLE TO CARRY A GUN INTO
SCHOOL IF YOU ARE AN
ADMINISTRATOR YOU SHOULD BE ABLE
TO PROTECT YOURSELF.
AT THIS TIME THE NRA ITSELF
ISN'T WEIGHING IN.
EVERYTHING IS QUIET ON THAT
FRONT.
THEY ARE WAITING, AS THEY SAID,
UNTIL THEY GET ALL THE FACTS
BEFORE THEY COMMENT ON WHAT HAS
HAPPENED HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
IF IT SEEMS LIKE PUBLIC OPINION
IS SHIFTING PERHAPS IT IS.
SOME OF THE LATEST POLLING
SUGGESTS IT HAS SHIFTED SOMEWHAT
IN TERMS OF MORE PRO GUN CONTROL
FEELINGS.
DEMOCRATIC LAWMAKERS CHANGING
THEIR MINDS, THOSE WHO SUPPORT
THE SECOND AMENDMENT AND DON'T
SUPPORT ADDITIONAL GUN CONTROL.
WHAT ABOUT THE NATIONAL RIFLE
ASSOCIATION AND WHEN IT DOES
BEGIN TO WEIGH IN?
IT IS A VERY POWERFUL LOBBY.
IS ANYTHING STANDING IN ITS WAY
AT THIS TIME?
HERE IS CAROL COSTELLO.
>> Reporter: IT IS A FAMILIAR
RITUAL FOR MANY POLITICIANS
SHOWING AND TELLING THEIR LOVE
OF THE GUN.
>> I AM A CATHOLIC DEER HUNTER.
I AM HAPPY TO BE CLINGING TO MY
GUNS AND MY RELIGION.
>> Reporter: DON'T THINK THIS
THING IS LIMITED TO GUN LOVING
REPUBLICANS.
DEMOCRATS RUN ON GUNS, TOO.
>> AS YOUR SENATOR I WILL
PROTECT OUR SECOND AMENDMENT
RIGHTS.
>> Reporter: BUT SUNDAY HOOK
TOUCHED WEST VIRGINIA'S
DEMOCRATIC SENATOR, A STRONG
SUPPORTER OF GUN RIGHTS.
>> WHO WOULD HAVE EVER THOUGHT
IN AMERICA OR ANYWHERE IN THE
WORLD THAT CHILDREN WOULD BE
SLAUGHTERED?
IT HAS CHANGED ME.
I DON'T KNOW OF ANYBODY THAT
GOES HUNTING WITH AN ASSAULT
RIFLE.
I DON'T KNOW PEOPLE THAT NEED
TEN, 20, 30 ROUND CLIPS.
>> Reporter: GRASS ROOTS
ORGANIZATIONS HAVE SPRUNG UP,
TOO, MARCHING ON THE NRA.
>> I AM GOING TO INTRODUCE IN
THE SENATE.
>> Reporter: SENATOR DIANNE
FEINSTEIN SWEARS SHE WILL
INTRODUCE GUN CONTROL
LEGISLATION IN A FEW WEEKS.
DON'T COUNT ON THE NRA JUST YET.
THEY'RE LYING LOW.
THEY KNOW THEY CAN'T WIN AN
ARGUMENT WHEN THE EMOTION OF THE
SUBJECT IS COMPLETELY TILTED TO
THE OPPOSITION.
IT IS WHY HE SAYS SO FAR THE NRA
HAS NOT COMMENTED ON SANDY
POINT.
IT IS THE SAME STRATEGY THE NRA
USED AFTER CONGRESS WOMAN
GABRIELLE GIFFORDS WAS SHOT.
INSTEAD OF PUBLICLY ARGUING THE
NRA MOBILIZED.
THE GUN RIGHTS ORGANIZATION
SPENT MORE ON LOBBYING IN 2011
THAN IT EVER HAD.
$2.5 MILLION.
AND IT PROMOTED PERSONAL SAFETY
THROUGH GUN OWNERSHIP LIKE IT
DID FOLLOWING BOB COSTAS'S
PASSIONATE PLEA FOR GUN CONTROL
AFTER JOE BELCHER SHOT HIS
GIRLFRIEND AND THEN HIMSELF.
>> HE WOULDN'T HAVE SAID A THING
IF THIS WOMAN SAVED HER LIFE BY
HAVING A FIREARM AVAILABLE.
>> Reporter: IT WASN'T LONG
BEFORE THE NFL AND GUN CONTROL
DIED DOWN.
AS FOR GUN CONTROL LEGISLATION
PASSED AFTER GABRIELLE GIFFORDS
WAS SHOT, ZERO.
AND CAROL COSTELLO JOINS ME LIVE
FROM ATLANTA.
VERY INTERESTING PIECE THAT YOU
PUT TOGETHER.
I AM CURIOUS ABOUT THE HISTORY
OF THE NRA'S REACTIONS AFTER
MASS SHOOTINGS.
WHAT IS THE TYPICAL M.O. OF THE
NRA AFTER THESE TRAGEDIES?
>> IN A WORD, NOTHING.
THE NRA DOESN'T COMMENT.
WHY SHOULD THEY?
YOU CAN'T WIN THIS ARGUMENT WITH
THE SPECTER OF 20 DEAD CHILDREN
HANGING IN THE AIR.
AS PAINFUL AS IT SOUNDS RIGHT
NOW, MEMORIES FADE.
SIX MONTHS FROM NOW PEOPLE WILL
LIKELY FEEL VERY DIFFERENTLY
ABOUT WHAT WENT DOWN IN NEWTOWN.
THE NRA PROBABLY WON'T COMMENT
THEN EITHER BUT IT WON'T NEED TO
BECAUSE ROUGHLY HALF THE
POPULATION STILL THINKS THE
ANSWERS TO TRAGEDIES IS MORE
GUNS, PROTECTION.
>> SO, CAROL, WHAT ABOUT THE
POWER OF THE NRA AS A LOBBY?
EVERYONE KNOWS IT IS
SIGNIFICANT.
YOU SAW SOME OF THE CAMPAIGN
PICTURES.
WHAT KIND OF POWER ARE WE
TALKING ABOUT WHEN IT COMES TO
MONEY AND NUMBERS?
>> IT IS NOT SO MUCH ABOUT THE
MONEY.
THE NRA HAS MILLIONS OF MEMBERS,
4 MILLION MEMBERS OR MORE.
THAT IS LIKE HAVING 4 MILLION
VOTES IN YOUR POCKET.
SO LEGISLATORS, LAWMAKERS ARE
ELECTED AND KNOW THAT.
THEY ARE TALKING ABOUT REAL
VOTES THEY MAY LOSE IF THEY PASS
GUN CONTROL LEGISLATION.
THAT IS THE POWER OF THE NRA.
>> CAROL COSTELLO REPORTING FOR
US LIVE IN ATLANTA.
THANK YOU FOR THAT INSIGHTFUL
REPORTING.
AND WHEN WE COME BACK, HOW DO
YOU DEAL WITH GRIEF WHEN THERE
IS ALMOST NO WAY TO DEAL WITH
IT?
WE HAVE ONE VERY, VERY SMALL
CONTRIBUTION THAT WE ARE GOING
TO SHOW YOU IN THE WAY OF FOUR
LEGGED FRIENDS.
QUESTIONS?
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
WITH ODOR FREE ASPERCREME.
POWERFUL MEDICINE
RELIEVES PAIN FAST,
WITH NO ODOR.
SO ALL YOU NOTICE IS RELIEF.
ASPERCREME.
>>> SOME OF THE STORIES THAT ARE
EMERGING HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT OF THE DAY THE
GUNMAN OPENED FIRE IN THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL ARE
NOTHING SHORT OF UNBELIEVABLE.
IN FACT, SIX LITTLE CHILDREN RAN
FROM THE SCHOOL IN THE MIDST OF
A SHOOTING AFTER WITNESSING
THEIR OWN TEACHER, VICTORIA SOTO
BEING GUNNED DOWN RIGHT BEFORE
THEIR EYES.
SOMEHOW THEY ESCAPED THAT
CLASSROOM AND RAN FOR THEIR
LIVES AND DIDN'T STOP RUNNING
AFTER THEY GOT OFF SCHOOL
PROPERTY.
THEY RAN DOWN THE STREET AND RAN
TO A NEIGHBOR.
THEY RAN ON TO HIS LAWN AND THEN
THEY STOPPED.
HE HAD NO IDEA WHAT HE WAS
WITNESSING UNTIL HE CAME OUT AND
ASKED WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE.
HIS NAME IS GENE ROSEN AND HE
SPOKE EXCLUSIVELY TO ERIN
BURNETT LAST NIGHT.
>> THEY WERE SITTING SO NICELY.
BUT THEN I SAW A MAN IN A VERY
AGITATED WAY SAYING IT IS GOING
TO BE ALL RIGHT.
HE KEPT RAISING HIS VOICE.
I THOUGHT TO MYSELF STRANGE.
AND I CAME TO THE CHILDREN.
AND THEY WERE CRYING AND
MORTIFIED.
AND IT WAS A SCHOOL BUS DRIVER
WITH THEM.
I INVITED THEM INTO THE HOUSE.
AND SHE SAID THAT AN INCIDENT AT
THE SCHOOL.
I HAD NO IDEA WHAT IT WAS.
>> Reporter: AND THE CHILDREN,
HOW DID THEY FIND THE WORDS TO
TELL YOU?
BECAUSE THEY TOLD YOU, RIGHT?
>> THEY JUST START TALKING.
THE TWO BOYS MOSTLY TALKED AND
THEY SAID WE CAN'T GO BACK TO
THAT SCHOOL.
WE CAN'T GO BACK.
OUR TEACHER IS DEAD.
WHAT ARE WE GOING TO DO?
WE DON'T HAVE A TEACHER.
THEY WERE SO BRAVE AND THEY WERE
SO GOOD.
I BROUGHT DOWN SOME TOYS FROM MY
GRAND SON'S TOY CHEST AND I GAVE
THEM SOME JUICE.
AND THEY CALLED THEIR PARENTS.
THEY WERE VERY BRAVE AND VERY
GOOD.
AND I WAS AMAZED.
I WAS ASTOUNDED AT WHAT THEY
WERE TELLING ME.
SOMETHING HAPPENED WITH ONE OF
THE BOYS OUT OF THIS GRIEF IN
THIS CARNAGE AND HE STOPPED.
AND HE BECAME VERY COMPOSED.
AND ALL OF A SUDDEN HE STOPPED
AND HE LOOKED AT ME AND HE SAID
JUST SAYING, YOUR HOUSE IS VERY
SMALL.
I THOUGHT WHAT A BRIGHT,
WONDERFUL BOY.
AND HE JUST BROUGHT TO ALL OF US
A RESPITE FRAME ALL OF THIS
DARKNESS.
I WANT TO SEE THESE KIDS.
I HOPE THEIR PARENTS WILL CALL
ME.
I WANT TO PUT MY ARMS AROUND
THEM AND TELL THEM THAT I LOVE
THEM.
I WANT THE CHILDREN TO BE THE
BASIS FOR OUR SOLUTION.
>> THAT'S GENE ROSEN SPEAKING
WITH OUR ERIN BURNETT.
THOSE CHILDREN WILL BE GOING
BACK TO SCHOOL BUT THEY WILL BE
GOING TO A NEW SCHOOL AND WILL
NOT BE SEEING THEIR TEACHER
AGAIN.
VICTORIA SOTO IS SET TO BE
BURIED TOMORROW.
THERE ARE A NUMBER OF FUNERALS
THIS WEEK.
HERS IS AMONG THEM.
WE ARE BACK AFTER THIS.
Song: "Yeah Yeah"
Label: Universal]
♪ Everybody well don't
you know it's me now? ♪
♪ Yeah who's it,
who's it huh? ♪
♪ Willy's back with a
brand new beat now, ♪
♪ Yeah doin' it doin' it up!
♪ Heyyy yeah, tryin'
to bite my style! ♪
♪ Heyyy yeah, how you
like me now? ♪
♪ Na na na na na na na na
♪ And everybody go uh!
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
>>> ONE OF THE BRIGHT SPOTS THAT
WE'VE BEEN ABLE TO FINE SENSE
WE'VE BEEN HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT A GROUP THAT'S COME
FROM ILLINOIS AND BROUGHT WITH
THEM A NUMBER OF FOUR-LEGGED
FRIENDS CALLED COMFORT DOGS.
THIS IS LUTHER, THE COMFORT DOG
WITH TIM HEADSLER HIS HANDLER.
I'VE BEEN SEEING YOUR WORK AND
THE DOG'S WORK.
IF YOU COULD FOR THE AUDIENCE
WHO MIGHT BE SEEING COMFORT DOGS
FOR THE FIRST TIME IT SOUNDS
OBVIOUS, WHAT IS A COMFORT DOG?
>> A COMFORT DOG COMES AND
BRINGS COMFORT.
THEY'RE LIKE A LIVING TEDDY
BEAR, IN SOME ASPECTS OR A FURRY
COUNSELOR.
>> LITERALLY YOU'RE INVITING
PEOPLE TO --
>> YEAH.
>> AND THEY'RE OBVIOUSLY VERY
SAFE BECAUSE YOU -- WE TEACH OUR
CHILDREN YOU CAN'T COME FACE TO
FACE WITH A PUPPY DOG BUT THESE
YOU CAN?
>> THEY HAVE A SIGN THAT SAYS
"PLEASE PET ME" THAT'S WHAT THEY
ARE HERE FOR.
THAT'S WHAT THEY LIVE FOR.
THEY LOVE TO BE LOVED AND GIVE
LOVE.
>> MY LORD, THEY'RE BEAUTIFUL.
AND YOU BROUGHT 12 OF THESE DOGS
WITH YOU?
>> RIGHT.
WE DID.
SOME HAD TO GO BACK EARLY THIS
MORNING BECAUSE OF A SITUATION
IN THE CHICAGO AREA.
WE HAVE EIGHT NOW AND A COUPLE
MORE COMING IN TO RELIEVE.
WE HAVE DOGS HERE THIS WEEK.
>> WHEN YOU GOT HERE, DID YOU
KNOW RIGHT AWAY WHERE TO GO, WHO
TO SEE OR DID YOU SHOW UP AND
WAIT FOR INSTRUCTIONS?
>> LUTHER CHURCH CHARITIES, OUR
CHURCH IS CHRIST THE KING WE
WORK THROUGH THEM AND CONNECT
WITH PEOPLE IN THE TOWN.
WE HAVE DOGS AT THE HIGH SCHOOL
RIGHT NOW.
>> WYOU'VE DONE THIS BEFORE.
HERE FOR HURRICANE SANDY.
>> HURRICANE SANDY, JOPLIN, WE
ALSO DEPLOY VOLUNTEERS OUT IN
DISASTER SITUATIONS.
>> CAN I ASK YOU, DO YOU NOTICE
A DIFFERENCE BETWEEN HOW
CHILDREN RESPOND AND GROWN-UPS
RESPONSE WHEN IT COMES TO THE
DOG?
>> ABOUT THE SAME.
BOTH COME TOWN AND PET, SOME
SHOW EMOTION, SOME WILL GET DOWN
ON THE GROUND WITH THE DOGS.
DOGS AT HIGH SCHOOL ARE
BASICALLY LAYING DOWN WITH KIDS
LAYING AROUND THEM ALL WITH
THEIR HAND ON THE DOG.
>> THAT IS RIGHT?
>> PETTING THE DOGS, MASSAGING
THE DOGS.
DOGS ARE LOVING IT.
>> I SAY I WANT TO COME BACK AS
A COMFORT DOG.
I'VE SEEN EVERYBODY COMING UP
AND SCRUBBING YOUR EARS AND
GIVING LOTS OF LOVE.
THERE'S A CERTAIN DOG YOU CHOOSE
AS A PUPPY AND YOU HAVE A TEST
TO GET RIGHT DOG TO BE SAFE AS
COMñGdmZDOG.
>> 5 1/2 DOG WE SEE THEIR
TEMPERAMENT.
IF THEY HAVE A TEMPERAMENT THAT
ALLOWS YOU TO DO THAT, THAT
STARTS THE TRAINING PROCESS.
WE TRAIN OUR DOGS AS SERVICE
DOGS NOT THAT WE USE THEM AS
SERVICE DOGS AS DISABLED BUT
THEY'RE TRAINED NOT BARK, BITE,
JUMP.
>> IF THEY WIGGLE, YOU KNOW THAT
THEY'VE GOT A TEMPERAMENT THAT
MIGHT NOT BE BEST FOR THIS LINE
OF WORK?
>> SO, FROM THAT POINT WE SPEND
PERSONAL TRAINER WITH A DOG FOR
EIGHT MONTHS TO A YEAR AND DO
THE FINAL TRAINING AND PLACE
THEM IN CHURCHES AND SCHOOLS.
>> THANK YOU FOR COMING AND
TALKING TO ME.
THANK YOU FOR BRINGING YOUR
DOGS.
THANK YOU FOR COMING TO THIS
COMMUNITY.
GOD BLESS YOU AND YOUR LUTHERAN
CHURCH CHARITIES.
JOINING US, LIKE I SAID, ONE
BRIGHT SPOT IN A VERY SAD STORY.
WE ARE BACK AFTER THIS.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN IT COMES TO
THE FINANCIAL OBSTACLES
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAND.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
I just served my mother-in-law
your Chicken Noodle soup
but she loved it so much...
I told her it was homemade.
Everyone tells
a little white lie now and then.
But now she wants
my recipe
[ clears his throat ]
[ softly ]
She's right behind me isn't she?
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
>>> THE KIDS IN NEWTOWN WILL BE
RETURNING TO SCHOOL TODAY, THE
KIDS FROM SANDY HOOK WILL NOT BE
BE BECAUSE THEIR GOING TO COME
HERE TO THE MONROE MIDDLE SCHOOL
CAMPUS, SPECIFICALLY LOOK TO THE
LEFT, THE CHALK HILL SCHOOL.
THAT WAS A SCHOOL BECAUSE OF
DECLINING ENROLLMENT CLOSED DOWN
AND SET TO REOPEN AS A COMMUNITY
CENTER.
BUT NOW MONROE COUNTY HAS
DECIDED TO AVAIL ITS SERVICES TO
KIDS FROM SANDY HOOK.
LOOK ACROSS THE STREET AT THE
SIGN THAT HAS JUST SHOWN UP.
WELCOME SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
IT'S REALLY HEARTWARMING TO SEE
THAT.
HERE'S HOW IT'S GOING TO WORK.
THEY'RE NOT GOING TO BE HERE
TODAY.
WE DON'T KNOW WHEN THEY'RE GOING
TO BE HERE.
IF YOU LOOK UP THERE, THERE'S A
POLICE OFFICER WHO IS BLOCKING
THE ENTRANCE TO THE MEDIA.
WE WANT TO BE RESPECTFUL.
THEY'RE ALLOWING TEACHERS THAT
ARE GOING INTO AN ADJACENT
MIDDLE SCHOOL AND ALSO PEOPLE
WHO ARE MOVING ALL OF THE
CONTENTS FROM SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY ACTUALLY INTO CHALK
HILL WHEN THESE CHILDREN ARRIVE