WE CAN'T TALK ABOUT IT ANYMORE.
WE HAVE TO START DOING THINGS IN
AMERICA.
>> THANK YOU FOR JOINING ME.
YOU HAVE ALL BEEN THROUGH HORROR
STORIES OF YOUR OWN AND THIS
MUST HAVE BROUGHT BECOME
HORRIFYING MEMORIES.
PRESIDENT OBAMA TALKED ABOUT IN
A MOVING EMOTIONAL WAY AND IT IS
TIME THAT AMERICAN PLIXS DID
SOMETHING INSTEAD OF WORRYING
ABOUT THE GUN LOBBY WHO MAKE
MILLIONS AND BILLIONS OF DOLLARS
IN WHAT OFTEN LEADS TO APPALLING
DEATH.
IT IS TIME FOR MORAL CONVICTION
AND COURAGE.
STAY WITH CNN ALL WEEKEND LONG.
THE LATEST ON THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
WE WILL BE BACK WITH A SPECIAL
EDITION OF PIERS MORGAN TONIGHT.
AC 360 STARTS NOW.
THERE IS ONLY ONE STORY TONIGHT.
YOU KNOW WHAT IT IS.
WE HAVE NEW DETAILS TO TELL BUT
AND WE WON'T PRETEND WE
UNDERSTAND IT ANY BETTER THAN
AFTER IT HAPPENED.
IT IS A HORROR BEYOND WORDS.
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, KIDS AS
YOUNG AS 5 YEARS OLD, THE SECOND
DEADLIEST SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
THIS COUNTRY.
20 LITTLE CHILDREN, SEVEN ADULTS
KILLED PLUS THE SHOOTER WHO TOOK
HIS OWN LIFE.
NALL A CLOSE-KNIT QUIET
COMMUNITY, 90 MINUTE DRIVE FROM
NEW YORK.
WE WILL GIVE YOU THE LATEST
INFORMATION, BUT WHAT WE WILL
NOT DO IS REPEAT THE SHOOTER'S
NAME OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
AS HAS BEEN DONE THROUGHOUT THE
DAY.
WE DON'T WANT HISTORY TO
REMEMBER THIS MURDERER BUT THE
VICTIMS, THE TEACHERS, THE
CHILDREN.
THOSE WHOSE LIVES HAVE BEEN SO
UNFAIRLY TAKEN.
WE HAVE A TEAMWORKING ON THE
TRAGEDY AND WE HAVE SOLEDAD
O'BRIEN ON THE SCENE.
THERE VIGILS TONIGHT.
THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN TRYING TO
COME TO GRIPS WITH WHAT HAPPENED
HERE.
BEHIND US, THIS MORNING.
RIGHT NOW, RIGHT NOW, THIS IS
STILL AN ACTIVE CRIME SCENE.
THAT MEANS THAT MANY OF THE
BODIES ARE LYING STILL WHERE
THEY FELL INSIDE OF THAT SCHOOL,
INCLUDING THE BODY OF A KILLER.
WE WANT TO AT LEAST TELL YOU HIS
NAME.
IT IS ADAM LANZA.
AS ANDERSON SAID WE ARE NOT
GOING TO REPEAT IT MUCH TONIGHT
AT ALL.
HIS MOTHER TAUGHT AT THE SCHOOL.
SHE WAS FOUND DEAD AT THE FAMILY
HOME.
.
IT'S UNCLEAR HOW SHE DIED OR
WHEN SHE DIED.
>> THE POLICE SAY IT IS AN
ACTIVE CRIME SCENE THAN AND THEY
TOLD US THEY THOUGHT BY SUNDAY
THEY WOULD BE ABLE TO HAVE THE
CRIME SCENE PART OF IT, THE
INVESTIGATION AT LEAST THAT
PORTION OF IT WRAPPED UP.
IT MIGHT BE AS SOON AS TOMORROW
MORNING.
AS YOU CAN IMAGINE, KNOWING THAT
YOUR CHILD HAS PERISHED INSIDE
OF THAT SCHOOL AND YOU CAN'T
EVEN GO AND GET A BODY.
IT WOULD BE A HORRIFIC THING.
>> LET'S HOPE THE CHILDREN ARE
BROUGHT HOME SOON.
WE KNOW THE MOTHER OF THE
SHOOTER LEGALLY PURCHASED THE
WEAPONS THAT WERE USED.
HLN'S RITA COSBY SAID HE BROKE
HIS WAY IN TO THE SCHOOL, TWO
SEMIAUTOMATIC HANDGUNS AND A
BUSHMASTER.
THE BROTHER WAS TAKEN IN TO
CUSTODY FOR QUESTIONING.
THEY DID NOT LABEL HIM A
SUSPECT.
THERE'S A LOT TO TELL YOU ABOUT
THIS HOUR BUT LET'S START AT THE
BEGINNING.
>> INDIVIDUAL I HAVE ON THE
PHONE IS CONTINUING TO HEAR WHAT
HE BELIEVES TO BE GUN FIRE.
>> THE FIRST WORD WAS CHILLING.
IT ONLY GOT WORSE.
>> THEY ARE REPORTING MULTIPLE
FATALITIES INVOLVED IN THE
SHOOTING AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
>> WITH EACH NEW REPORT THE
HORROR DEEPENED.
>> REPORTS SAY THE NUMBER OF
DEAD CLOSER TO 30 THAN TO 20 AND
SADLY MOST OF THEM ARE CHILDREN.
>> EVERY DETAIL, EVERY FACT
BROUGHT MORE SADNESS.
EACH FRESH PIECE OF INFORMATION
A PART OF THE PICTURE.
A SCHOOL, KINDERGARTEN THROUGH
4th GRADE.
A SANCTION WARE SUPPO
.
>> THE SCHOOL WENT IN TO
LOCKDOWN.
>> A STUDENT'S TEENAGE
BIG BROTHER DESCRIBING THE
SOUNDS OF GUNMEN ON THE LOOSE AT
SANDY HOOK.
>> ON AND OFF DUTY TROOPERS
RESPONDED AND WITH NEWTOWN
POLICE IMMEDIATELY UPON ARRIVAL
ENTERED THE SCHOOL AND BEGAN A
COMPLETE SHOOTER'S SEARCH OF THE
BUILDING.
>> THEY ARRIVED TO CARNAGE AND
THE KILLER SAID A SOURCE WAS
DRESSED FOR BATTLE IN BLACK
FATIGUES AND ARMED FOR MASS
MURDER WITH TWO PISTOLS AND A
MILITARY-STYLE RIFLE.
IN PARTS OF THE SCHOOL, STUDENTS
WERE TOLD TO HIDE IN CORNERS.
TEACHERS RISKED THEIR LIVES TO
PULL BOYS AND GIRLS TO SAFETY.
>> SO GRATEFUL TO THE TEACHER
WHO SAVED HIM.
>> THE TEACHER SAVED HIS LIFE?
>> SHE DEFINITELY DID.
HE HAD BULLETS GOING BY HIM AND
SHE GRABBED HIM AND ANOTHER
CHILD AND PULLED THEM INTO A
CLASSROOM.
>> EVENTUALLY THE KIDS WERE
EVACUATED TO A NEARBY FIRE HOUSE
WHERE FRANTIC PARENTS DESCENDED.
>> I'M STILL TERRIFY AND IN
SHOCK.
I DON'T KNOW EVERYTHING THAT
HAPPENED.
I KNOW THERE PEOPLE MISSING THAT
HAVE BEEN TAKEN TO THE HOSPITAL.
>> HIS SON WAS OKAY AND HIS
TEACHER WAS ALIVE, AS WELL.
20 OTHER CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS
WERE KILLED.
THE DEAD BELIEVED TO INCLUDE
SANDY HOOK'S SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST
AND THE PRINCIPAL.
POLICE DISCOVERED ANOTHER ADULT
VICTIM, THE GUNMAN'S MOTHER
REPORTEDLY AT HOME IN NEWTOWN.
THE GUNMAN TOO IS DEAD.
POLICE SAY THEY FIRED NO SHOTS.
A TIGHT-KNIT COMMUNITY INCLUDING
A NURSE WHO RUSHED TO HELP.
SHOCK AND DISTRAUGHT.
SGLUF BEEN CRYING.
>> YES.
>> BECAUSE OF WHAT YOU SAW
>> ONE OF THE COPS SAID IT'S THE
WORST THING HE HAD EVER SEEN IN
HIS ENTIRE CAREER, BUT WHEN THEY
TOLD THE PARENTS, ALL THE
PARENTS WERE WAITING FOR THEIR
CHILDREN TO COME OUT.
THEY THOUGHT THEY WERE STILL
ALIVE.
THERE WAS 20 PARENTS WHO WERE
TOLD THEIR CHILDREN ARE DEAD.
IT WAS AWFUL.
>> AWFUL AND LATE TODAY SPEAKING
FOR THE NATION, BUT ALSO AS A
FATHER, AN EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT
OBAMA FOUGHT BACK TEARS.
>> THIS EVENING MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT
IN AMERICA WILL DO.
HUG OUR CHILDREN TIGHTER AND
TELL THEM WE LOVE THEM AND WE
WILL REMIND EACH OTHER HOW
DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT THAT CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT.
AND THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT
NOW.
>> WE WILL BRING YOU ALL OF
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S COMMENTS LATER
ON IN THIS HOUR AHEAD.
AS ONE MOTHER SAID TOO MANY OF
OUR BABIES DIECHLTD WITH US ON
THE PHONE FROM NEWTOWN IS JANET
VOLMEI
VOLMER WHO TEACHES KINDERGARTEN
THERE.
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
>> I'M OKAY.
MY FAMILY IS HERE, AND THAT
HELPS.
MY HUSBAND CAME AND MY DOGS AND
SONS.
>> YOU WERE IN YOUR CLASSROOM.
>> I WAS IN MY CLASSROOM.
WHAT DID YOU HEAR?
>> WELL, ABOUT 9:30, 9:40, WE
HEARD NOISES AND THE
ANNOUNCEMENT SYSTEM WAS STILL
ON.
SO IT DIDN'T GO OFF.
SO YOU COULD HEAR WHAT SOUNDED
LIKE POPS, GUNSHOTS.
OF COURSE I'M NOT GOING TO TELL
THAT TO 5-YEAR-OLDS.
SO I SAID WE ARE GOING TO A SAFE
AREA AND WE READ A STORY AND
KEPT THEM CALM.
DID A LOCKDOWN DRILL.
CLOSED THE DOORS, COVERED THE
WINDOWS AND KEPT THE CHILDREN
WITH US.
I HAVE OTHER ADULTS.
>> I FIND THAT AMAZING THAT
FEARING THAT YOU HEAR GUNSHOTS
YOU WERE ABLE TO HAVE THE
COMPOSURE TO SIT DOWN AND READ
TO YOUR STUDENTS.
THAT'S EXTRAORDINARY.
>> THAT'S WHAT YOU HAVE TO DO
WITH 5-YEAR-OLDS BECAUSE YOU
CAN'T LOSE IT.
YOU JUST -- I HAVE BEEN DOING
THIS A LONG TIME.
IT IS MY 18th YEAR OF TEACHING.
I DIDN'T KNOW.
THERE WAS NO ANNOUNCEMENT OF
WHAT WAS GOING ON.
MY INSTINCT WAS IT WASN'T GOOD.
SO WE KEPT THEM CALM.
WE STAYED IN THE ROOM UNTIL
THERE WAS BANGING AT THE DOOR,
WHICH WERE THE POLICE AND THE
TROOPERS OR WHOEVER WAS THERE
AND THEY HAD US EXIT THE
BUILDING AND TOLD THE CHILDREN
TO COVER THEIR EYES AND WALK IN
A LINE AND LEAVE THE BUILDING
AND THAT'S WHEN WE WENT TO THE
FIRE HOUSE.
WE WERE ALL SAFE.
I HAD 19 CHILDREN IN THE ROOM
WITH ME AND THANK GOODNESS ALL
OF THEIR PARENTS WERE ABLE TO
COME AND PICK THEM UP AND TAKE
THEM HOME.
>> AS YOU WERE READING TO THEM,
DID THE KIDS REALIZE SOMETHING
WAS GOING ON OR DID THEY THINK
IT WAS A DRILL LIKE BEFORE?
>> IT DIDN'T SEEM A NATURAL
THING, ALTHOUGH WE DO PRACTICE
DRILLS.
WE JUST SAID, WE'RE NOT REALLY
SURE, BUT WE'RE GOING TO BE SAFE
BECAUSE WE ARE SITTING OVER HERE
AN WE ARE ALL TOGETHER.
AND THAT'S -- AS WE GOT TO THE
FIRE HOUSE LATER ON, AS A LOT OF
THE EVENTS BEGAN TO UNFOLD
THROUGHOUT THE DAY I THINK SOME
OF THEM REALIZED THE MAGNITUDE
OF WHAT WAS GOING ON.
THEY SAW OTHER PEOPLE UPSET.
WE HELD THEM CLOSE UNTIL THEIR
PARENTS CAME AND WE RELEASED
THEM AN MY ROOM, MY CHILDREN
WERE ALL ACCOUNTED FOR AND SAFE
IN MY KINDERGARTEN CLASSROOM.
>> IT'S SO, FOR ALL OF US IT IS
SO INCOMPREHENSIBLE AND
OBVIOUSLY YOU KNEW THE CHILDREN
AND THE FAMILIES INVOLVED.
YOUR COLLEAGUES HAVE LOST THEIR
LIVES.
I'M NOT GOING TO CERTAINLY ASK
ABOUT THE KIDS BUT WHAT DO YOU
WANT THE RLD TO KNOW ABOUT
YOUR COLLEAGUES.
>> WE HEARD A LOT OF THINGS AT
THE FIRE HOUSE.
PEOPLE WERE TEXTING NEWS REPORTS
AND THIS ONE AND THAT ONE.
I'M SURE -- I'M NOT SURE STILL
OF THE MAGNITUDE OF WHO EVERYONE
IS BECAUSE I HEAR SIX OR SEVEN
ADULTS AND MANY CHILDREN, AND I
KNOW THOSE FIRST GRADERS WERE
CHILDREN I HAD IN MY ROOM LAST
YEAR.
SO THOSE PARENTS WERE SHOWING UP
TODAY AND THEY COULDN'T FIND
THEIR CHILDREN AND THEY WERE ALL
TAKEN TO SEPARATE ROOMS.
SO, I DON'T KNOW WHO THEY ARE
BUT I'M SURE AS THE DAYS UNFOLD
IT WILL NOT BE GOOD NEWS FOR
MANY OF THOSE PEOPLE.
>> IT'S REALLY BEYOND WORDS.
AND I APPRECIATE YOU TAKING A
MOMENT TO TALK TO US TONIGHT.
REALLY IS.
JANET, THANK YOU FOR YOUR
COMPOSURE.
IT IS EXTRAORDINARY WHAT YOU DID
AND THE OTHER COLLEAGUES OF
YOURS.
>> SOME OF THOSE TEACHERS WERE
HEROS.
SOME OF THEM IN THE FRONT
BUILDING.
WE HAD ONE TEACHER WHO WAS ON
THE NEWS EARLIER.
SHE LOCKED EVERYBODY IN THE
BATHROOM AND WOULDN'T OPEN THE
DOOR.
WE DO THIS AS TEACHERS.
WE ARE TRAINED.
WE DO HAVE DRILLS.
WE TALK TO THE KIDS IN CASE
SOMETHING WERE TO HAPPEN.
THIS IS WHAT WE DO AND THAT IS
WHAT HAPPENED TODAY.
EVERYBODY JUST INSTINCTIVELY
KEPT THEIR CHILDREN SAFE.
>> THERE'S A LOT OF TEACHERS
AROUND THE COUNTRY THAT I THINK
OF AS HEROS EVERY DAY AND TODAY
FRANKLY YOU SHOWED THAT AND ALL
OF YOUR COLLEAGUES SHOWED THAT.
SO THANK YOU.
>> I WISH YOU PEACE AND STRENGTH
IN THE DIFFICULT DAYS AHEAD.
AMY SEAVER IS JOINING US ON THE
PHONE.
HER DAUGHTER IS A FIRST GRADER
AT SANDY HOOK.
SHE AND OTHER PARENTS GOT THE
CHILLING PHONE CALL SAYING THE
SCHOOL WAS ON LOCKDOWN.
HOW IS YOUR DAUGHTER DOING, YOUR
FAMILY.
HOW ARE YOU HOLDING UP?
>> OKAY.
IT'S A VERY ROUGH NIGHT HERE
WHEN YOUR FIRST GRADER GOES TO
BED AND SAYS, MOMMY, IS ANYONE
FROM MY LAST YEAR ARE THEY ALL
OKAY?
ARE THEY ALL OKAY AND YOU LOOK
AT THEM AND SAY I'M NOT REALLY
SURE.
IT IS A ROUGH NIGHT TO TELL THAT
TO YOUR 7-YEAR-OLD.
IT'S VERY, SAD NIGHT FOR THIS
TOWN AND A LOT OF FAMILIES HERE.
>> HAS YOUR DAUGHTER WANTED TO
TALK ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED OR
FIRST GRADE -- DO THEY WANT TO
TALK?
>> SHE ASKED A LOT OF QUESTIONS
ABOUT THE PRINCIPAL.
SHE GOT WIND QUICKLY THAT
SOMETHING WAS WRONG WITH THE
PRINCIPAL.
WHICH WE DIDN'T TELL HER UNTIL
JUST NOW THAT YES, SHE WAS
DEFINITELY HURT AND IT WASN'T
GOOD.
IT'S TAKING HER A WHILE.
I THINK TOMORROW WILL BE
PROBABLY HARDER FOR HER.
I ALSO HAVE A FIFTH GRADER WHO
CAME OFF THE BUS CRY CANNING
BECAUSE SHE HAD A SISTER WHO SHE
WAS WORRIED ABOUT.
JUST BASICALLY LEFT THAT SCHOOL
A FEW MONTHS AGO.
I THINK FOR A LOT OF THOSE KIDS
THEY ARE KIND OF OLDER AND CAN
GET IT A LITTLE FASTER, EVEN
THOUGH THEY WEREN'T IN IT.
SO THE QUESTIONS I THINK ARE
COMING.
THEY ARE NOT REALLY HERE YET,
ESPECIALLY FOR THE LITTLER ONES.
IT STARTED TONIGHT AS I PUT THEM
TO BED.
>> DO YOU KNOW HOW YOU WILL
ANSWER THOSE QUESTIONS.
A LOT OF PARENTS AROUND THE
WORLD WHOSE CHILDREN WILL BE
ASKING THEM QUESTIONS.
DO YOU THINK YOU KNOW WHAT YOU
WILL SAY?
>> UNFORTUNATELY WE HAVE BEEN
THROUGH A BIT OF TRAUMA IN OUR
OWN LIFE.
FOR ME AND I CAN'T SPEAK FOR
OTHER MOMS OR MOMS AROUND THE
WORLD BUT FOR MY FAMILY, I SPEAK
QUIETLY AND TRUTHFULLY.
AND I TRY TO ANSWER THE
QUESTIONS THAT ARE ASKED AND
GIVE THE INFORMATION THAT THEY
ASK FOR WITHOUT A LOT OF DETAIL.
I DEFINITELY DON'T LIE.
I WAS POINT BLANK ASKED TONIGHT
IF THE PRINCIPAL WAS OKAY AND I
SAID NO AND SHE ASKED IF SHE WAS
DEAD AND I SAID YES.
I DON'T LIE TO MY CHILDREN.
I TRY NOT TO OFFER TOO MUCH
BECAUSE I'M NOT SURE WHAT THEY
KNOW.
SO I TRY TO SIT BACK AND WAIT
FOR THEM TO ASK BUT IF THEY ASK
ME A QUESTION I GIVE THEM AN
HONEST ANSWER.
UNFORTUNATELY FOR A LOT OF US IN
TOWN, THE ANSWERS ARE NOT GOOD.
>> THE PRINCIPAL --
>> OUR HEARTS ARE SAD TONIGHT.
I DON'T THINK THAT ANYONE CAN
ANSWER THESE QUESTIONS EASILY.
THEY ARE DEFINITELY NOT FUN
ANSWERS.
>> I'VE HEARD SO MANY GREAT
THINGS ABOUT THE PRINCIPAL, DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG
AND THE FACT THAT YOUR CHILD WAS
ACTING ABOUT HER.
WHAT DO YOU WANT PEOPLE TO KNOW
ABOUT DAWN?
>> VERY LOVELY, COMPASSIONATE
WOMAN.
EXTREMELY HELPFUL, AS A CHIR ON
ONE OF THE PTA COMMITTEES COULD
NOT HAVE COME OUT TO SUPPORT ME
BETTER THIS YEAR.
I NEEDED SUPPORT THIS YEAR AND
SHE WAS THE FIRST ONE ON MY
TEAM, THE FIRST ONE TO HELP.
THE FIRST ONE TO BE THERE.
NEVER SAW HER WITHOUT A SMILE.
YOU KNOW, JUST IN MY DAUGHTER'S
CLASSROOM THIS WEEK READING A
BOOK TO THE KIDS.
VERY, VERY LOVELY.
VERY LOVELY WOMAN AND DEFINITELY
HAD THE CHILDREN, I BELIEVE HAD
THE CHILDREN'S BEST INTENTIONS
ALL THE TIME.
SHE WAS ALWAYS LOOKING OUT FOR
THEM.
VERY SAD DAY.
>> YEAH.
YOU MUST BE EXHAUSTED AND I'M
GOING TO LET YOU GO.
I APPRECIATE YOU TALKING
TONIGHT.
I REALLY JUST WISH YOU AND YOUR
FAMILY A LOT OF STRENGTH.
THANK YOU.
>> MY FAMILY IS ONE OF THE LUCKY
ONES, ANDERSON, UNFORTUNATELY
THERE'S A LOT OF PEOPLE THAT
AREN'T SO LUCKY TONIGHT IN TOWN.
BUT THANK YOU.
WE PRAY FOR ALL OF THE FAMILIES
THAT ARE OUT THERE TONIGHT.
>> I THINK THERE'S A LOT OF
PRAYERS AN THE WORLD FOR THOSE
FAMILIES.
AMY, THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> THAT IS FRANKLY UNBELIEVABLE.
LET'S GO TO SOL DAD.
-- SOLEDAD.
>> IT REALLY IS.
IT IS ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE TO
FATHOM WHAT THE PEOPLE OF
NEWTOWN ARE GOING THROUGH RIGHT
NOW AND SO MANY LIVES WERE LOST.
SO MANY OTHER PEOPLE'S LIVES
WERE CHANGED FOREVER.
FRIENDS AND NEIGHBORS AND EVEN
IN SOME CASES STRANGERS GATHERED
AND CONTINUE TO GATHER AT THIS
HOUR TO HOLD EACH OTHER AND CRY
AND TO REMEMBER.
THERE WAS A VIGIL TONIGHT.
TOOK PLACE AT A LOCAL CHURCH.
JASON HAS BEEN THERE ALL DAY AND
THROUGH THE NIGHT AND HE HAS AN
UPDATE ON HOW THAT WENT.
JASON, THE MOOD HAS TO BE SO
SAD.
TELL ME A LITTLE BIT ABOUT
TONIGHT'S VIGIL.
>> YOU KNOW, I HAVE SEEN A LOT
OF EMOTIONAL THINGS THROUGHOUT
MY LIFE.
TONIGHT WAS -- IT'S REALLY HARD
TO EXPLAIN.
THE VIGIL HERE TONIGHT, SO MANY
PEOPLE CAME OUT HERE SOLEDAD.
THERE WASN'T ENOUGH ROOM FOR
EVERYONE.
THEY STOOD OUTSIDE IN THE
FREEZING COLD.
HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE STOOD IN
SILENCE AND LISTENED.
WHEN THE VIGIL LED OUT, ALL OF
THOSE STANDING OUTSIDE WENT
INSIDE AND YOU HEARD SOME
SINGING AT ONE POINT.
GROUPS BROKE OFF IN TO SEPARATE
GROUPS AND STARTED SINGING.
PEOPLE CAME HERE TONIGHT AND I
KNOW YOU HEARD ANDERSON GIVE THE
EMOTIONAL INTERVIEW.
PEOPLE CAME LOOKING FOR ANSWERS
LIKE THAT MOTHER WAS TRYING TO
GIVE ANSWERS TO HER DAUGHTER.
IT'S DIFFICULT.
IT'S VERY TOUGH TO DRY TRY TO
GET THOSE ANSWERS AT THIS TIME.
PEOPLE CAME HERE LOOKING FOR
THAT.
THEY CAME HERE TO LEAN ON EACH
OTHER AND THEY TURNED TO THEIR
FAITH.
THIS IS THE KIND OF PLACE WHERE
SO MANY PEOPLE THAT CAME OUT
HERE TONIGHT KNEW SOMEONE.
THEY KNEW ONE OF THE FACULTY
MEMBERS, KNEW THE CHILDREN.
TOLD A STORY ABOUT A LITTLE GIRL
WHO LOST HER LIFE WHO WAS
SUPPOSED TO BE AT A CHRISTMAS
PAGEANT AND ANOTHER MAN WHO KNEW
THE PRINCIPAL AND SPOKE ABOUT
HER.
I WANT YOU TO LISTEN TO A LITTLE
BIT OF THAT CONVERSATION.
>> DAWN, THE PRINCIPAL AT SANDY
HOOK, I HAD DINNER WITH HER LAST
SPRING.
SHE WAS EXCITING, KBUB BRANT AND
INCREDIBLE EDUCATOR AND TO LOSE
SOMEBODY LIKE THAT IN THE
DISTRICT IS SAD BECAUSE THEY
LOST A LEADER TODAY AT SANDY
HOOK BUT THE PRAYERS ARE FOR OUR
COMMUNITY, AS WELL.
>> ONE OF THE OTHER POINTS HE
WANTED TO MAKE IS THIS WAS A
WOMAN WHO LOVED NOT ONLY HER
SCHOOL CAN AND HER JOB BUT ALL
OF THE CHILDREN AT THE SCHOOL,
AS WELL.
SOLEDAD.
>> I KNOW AUD CHANCE TO TALK TO
THE DEACON AND I'M SURE HE WILL
BE THE FOCUS OF MANY OF THE
QUESTIONS PEOPLE ARE HAVING.
WHAT DID HE TELL YOU?
>> IT WAS DIFFICULT FOR HIM HE
BECAME EMOTIONAL DURING OUR
CONVERSATION.
HE SAID AT LEAST A HUNDRED
PEOPLE CAME THROUGH THE CHURCH
DOORS THAT DAY.
THEY WERE LOOKING FOR ANSWERS AN
I ASKED HOW DO YOU PROVIDE
ANSWERS AND HE SAID IT IS TOO
SOON TO COME UP WITH A DEEP
PHILOSOPHICAL ANSWER OF WHY THIS
HAPPENED.
HE WAS FEELING THE EMOTION OF
WHAT HAPPENED AS WELL.
HE KNEW SOME OF THE CHILDREN
THAT WERE KILLED, INCLUDING SOME
OF THE FACULTY MEMBERS.
HE SPOKE ABOUT ONE CHILD IN
PARTICULAR.
HE REMEMBERED RECEIVING HER
FIRST COMMUNION HERE AT THE
CHURCH AND A CHILD WHO LEFT AN
IMPRESSION ON HIM AND HE
EXPLAINS THE REASON WHY.
>> I HEARD ONE OF THE VICTIMS,
I'M NOT SURE ABOUT IT, BUT I
HEARD ONE OF THE VICTIMS
RECENTLY.
IT WAS BIRTHDAY MONEY.
SHE GATHERED UP HER BIRTHDAY
GIFTS AND DONATED IT TO THE
PARISH TO GIVE IT TO THE
HURRICANE SANDY VICTIMS.
6 YEARS OLD.
SO THAT'S -- THAT MAKES IT VERY,
VERY PERSONAL.
AND VERY INTIMATE.
>> HIS STRUGGLE IS THAT HE HAS
TO BE A ROCK FOR THE COMMUNITY
NOW.
HE HAS TO TRY TO KEEP IT
TOGETHER AS MORE PEOPLE COME TO
HIM TO LEAN ON HIM FOR EMOTIONAL
SUPPORT.
I SAID WHAT DO YOU DO?
HE SAID I'M GOING TO GO HOME AND
HUG MY OWN DAUGHTER AND COME
BACK HERE AND BE THE SUPPORT
THAT THIS COMMUNITY NEEDS.
>> JASON CARROLL FOR US.
THANK YOU.
APPRECIATE THAT.
ANDERSON, AS JASON POINTS OUT IT
IS A QUESTION ARE ALL TRYING TO
GET AN ANSWER TO IT.
THE WHY BEHIND IT.
WE TALKED ABOUT THE SHOOT ER BUT
THE MOTIVATION IS THE THING THAT
I DON'T THINK THAT ANYONE IS
CLOSE TO UNDERSTANDING AT THIS
POINT.
>> YEAH.
AND MAY NEVER.
YOU KNOW, SOMETIMES THERE ISN'T
ANY WHY.
WE'LL CONTINUE TO INVESTIGATE.
APPRECIATE IT.
WE WILL COME BACK TO YOU
SHORTLY.
AUTHORITIES HAVE NOT YET
RELEASED THE NAMES OF THE
VICTIMS.
POLICE SAY THE PROCESS OF
IDENTIFICATION CONTINUES AT THIS
HOUR.
THE CHILDREN'S BODIES ARE STILL
INSIDE THE SCHOOL AND WILL BE
THROUGHOUT THE EVENING.
AS WE LEARN WHO THEY ARE, WE
WILL TELL YOU ABOUT THEM WHEN WE
LEARN ABOUT THEM AND WHEN THEIR
PARENTS WANT YOU TO KNOW ABOUT
THEM.
IT IS THE VICTIMS WE WANT
HISTORY TO REMEMBER AND HONOR.
ACCORDING TO THE WITNESS, THE
SCHOOL'S PRINCIPAL AND
PSYCHOLOGIST ARE AMONG THE DEAD.
YOU HEARD PARENTS TALK ABOUT
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG
.
SHE BECAME THE PRINCIPAL AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
2010.
SHE HAD 12 YEARS OF EXPERIENCE
AS A SCHOOL ADMINISTRATOR AND A
MOM RAISING TWO DAUGHTERS AND
THREE STEP DAUGHTERS ACCORDING
TO A LOCAL PAPER AND A LOT OF
FOLKS SAID SHE WAS PASSIONATE
ABOUT HER JOB, AN EXPERT ON
CURRICULUM, FUN BUT A FIRM
LEADER THEY SAID.
ONE SAID SHE WAS THE KIND OF
PERSON YOU WOULD WANTED TO
EDUCATE YOUR KIDS AND KIDS LOVE
HER.
THAT WAS HER.
SHE WROTE ABOUT HER LOVE OF
READING AND POSTED MESSAGES AND
PHOTOS ABOUT EVENTS AND
DEVELOPMENTS AT THE SCHOOL.
ON AUGUST 24th, SHE TWEETED
THIS.
SHE SAID WELCOMING OUR KINDERS
THIS MORNING.
74 NEW OPPORTUNITIES TO INSPIRE
LIFE-LONG LEARNING.
SHE WAS TALKING ABOUT THE NEW
KINDERGARTEN CLASS.
SHE HAD INSTALLED A NEW SECURITY
SYSTEM AT THE SCHOOL AND ALL
VISITORS HAD TO RING A DOORBELL
AT THE ENTRANCE AND WAIT TO BE
BUZZED IN AFTER THE DOORS
AUTOMATICALLY LOCKED AT 9:30
A.M.
THE GLASS ENTRANCE WAS SHOT OUT
OR SMASHED ALLOWING HIM IN THE
BUILDING.
WE DON'T HAVE PHOTOGRAPHS OF THE
OTHER VICTIMS, THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGI
PSYCHOLOGIST.
SHE HAD BEEN AT SANDY HOOK FOR
18 YEARS, UNDERGRADUATE DEGREE
IN PSYCHOLOGY AND MASTERS AND
SIX YEAR PROFESSIONAL DEGREE.
SHE WAS A WIFE AND MOM.
MARRIED TO HER HUSBAND BILL FOR
MORE THAN 30 YEARS.
TWO GROWN DAUGHTERS.
THE OLDEST WORKS AS A HIGH
SCHOOL CHORUS TEACHER IN NEW
JERSEY.
MARY SHERLOCK AND DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG
WE WILL REMEMBER THEM.
WHEN WE COME BACK, MORE ON
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S EMOTIONAL
REACTION TO THE SHOOTING.
WE WANT TO PLAY HIS COMMENTS AND
MORE FROM THE PARENTS, AS WELL.
>> IT'S NOT SOMETHING THAT YOU
SHAKE OFF VERY EASILY AND
CERTAINLY NOT FOR LITTLE PEOPLE
AND WE LOST A LOT OF BABIES
TODAY IN THIS TOWN.
AND THERE ARE A LOT OF VERY SAD
FAMILIES AND AS EVERYONE CAN
THINK, YOU NEVER THINK IT WILL
HAPPEN BUT IT HAPPENS ALL OVER
THE WORLD AT THIS POINT.
SantHo, Ho, Ho!anta!
Santa!
Want to see some magic?
Watch this! Merry Chr...
(Crash) Ow!
I landed on my keys.
Did you get that?
Oh yeah.
That was amazing.
Here you go.
That was a fun trick!
See? Santa's okay.
Walk it off Santa.
Share videos instantly
with S Beam.
On the Galaxy SIII
and Note II.
For a limited time get two flip
covers for the price of one.
Exclusively at Verizon.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
>>> DOESN'T EVEN SEEM REAL.
DOESN'T SEEM POSSIBLE.
IT'S LIKE YOU READ IT IN THE
PAPER, SEE IT IN THE NEWS, YOU
ARE LIKE OH, MY GOD, THAT POOR
FAMILY AND THEN SOMETHING
HAPPENS SO CLOSE TO HOME, IT'S
LIKE, I THINK I'M STILL IN SHOCK
TO BE HONEST WITH YOU.
>> A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE FEELING
THE SAME WAY TONIGHT, IN SHOCK.
THE MASSACRE INSIDE THE SCHOOL
IS THE DEADLIEST ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN AMERICAN HISTORY.
IN ALL OF THE WORDS HAVE BEEN
SPOKEN TODAY AND THE WORDS I'M
SPEAKING IN THIS HOUR SOUND SO
SMALL IN THE FACE OF THIS
HORROR.
20 CHILDREN, SEVEN ADULTS.
LAST NIGHT THEY WERE ALIVE
GETTING READY FOR ANOTHER DAY OF
SCHOOL.
AND TONIGHT THEY ARE GONE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SPOKE TO THE
NATION EARLIER.
WE PLAYED SOME OF IT BEFORE THE
TOP OF THE PROGRAM, BUT I THINK
IT IS WORTH HEARING ALL OF WHAT
HE SAID.
>> THIS AFTERNOON I SPOKE WITH
GOVERNOR MALLOY AND FBI DIRECTOR
MUELLER.
I OFFERED GOVERNOR MALLOY MY
CONDOLENCES ON BEHALF OF THE
NATION AND MADE IT CLEAR HE WILL
HAVE EVERY SINGLE RESOURCE HE
NEEDS TO INVESTIGATE THIS
HEINOUS CRIME, CARE FOR THE
VICTIMS, COUNSEL THEIR FAMILIES.
WE'VE ENDURED TOO MANY OF THESE
TRAGEDIES IN THE PAST FEW YEARS
AND EACH TIME I LEARN THE NEWS,
I REACT NOT AS A PRESIDENT BUT
AS ANYONE ELSE WOULD, AS A
PARENT.
AND THAT WAS ESPECIALLY TRUE
TODAY.
I KNOW THERE'S NOT A PARENT IN
AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, CHILDREN OF THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS.
MEN AND WOMEN WHO DEVOTED THEIR
LIVES TO HELPING OUR CHILDREN
FULFILL THEIR DREAMS.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN TODAY FOR
THE PARENTS, GRAND PARENT S,
SISTERS AND BROTHERS OF THESE
LITTLE CHILDREN AND FOR THE
FAMILIES OF THE ADULTS WHO WERE
LOST.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN FOR THE
PARENTS OF THE SURVIVORS AS
WELL.
FOR AS BLESSED AS THEY ARE TO
HAVE THEIR CHILDREN HOME
TONIGHT, THEY KNOW THAT THEIR
CHILDREN'S INNOCENCE HAS BEEN
TORN AWAY FROM THEM TOO EARLY
AND THERE ARE NO WORDS THAT WILL
EASE THEIR PAIN.
AS A COUNTRY, WE HAVE BEEN
THROUGH THIS TOO MANY TIMES.
WHETHER IT'S AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN OR A SHOPPING
MALL IN OREGON.
OR A TEMPLE IN WISCONSIN OR A
MOVIE THEATER IN AURORA OR A
STREET CORNER IN CHICAGO.
THESE NEIGHBORHOODS ARE OUR
NEIGHBORHOODS.
THESE CHILDREN ARE OUR CHILDREN.
WE WILL HAVE TO COMING TO AND
TAKE MEANINGFUL ACTION TO
PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE
REGARDLESS OF THE POLITICS.
THIS EVENING MICHELLE AND I WILL
DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT IN
AMERICA WILL DO WHICH IS HUG OUR
CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER AND
WILL TELL THEM WE LOVE THEM.
AND WE WILL REMIND EACH OTHER
HOW DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT THAT CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT.
AN THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT
NOW.
IN HARD DAYS TO COME, THE
COMMUNITY NEEDS US TO BE AT OUR
BEST AS AMERICANS, AND I WILL DO
EVERYTHING IN MY POWER, AS
PRESIDENT, TO HELP.
WHILE NOTHING CAN FILL THE SPACE
OF A LOST CHILD OR LOVED ONE,
ALL OF US CAN EXTEND A HAND TO
THOSE IN NEED TO REMIND THEM
THAT WE ARE THERE FOR THEM.
THAT WE ARE PRAYING FOR THEM,
THAT THE LOVE THEY FELT FOR
THOSE THEY LOST ENDURES NOT JUST
IN THEIR MEMORIES BUT ALSO IN
OURS.
MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF THE
VICTIMS.
AND IN THE WORDS OF SCRIPTURE,
HEAL THE BROKEN HEARTED AND BIND
UP THEIR WOUNDS.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA SPEAKING
EARLIER TODAY, NOT JUST AS
PRESIDENT BUT AS A FATHER OF TWO
DAUGHTERS.
DENISE'S DAUGHTER GOES TO SANDY
HOOK.
SHE WAS IN SCHOOL THIS MORNING.
WE SPOKE EARLIER TONIGHT.
>> DENISE, I CANNOT IMAGINE WHAT
THIS DAY HAS BEEN LIKE FOR YOU,
OBVIOUSLY FOR YOUR CHILD.
HOW IS YOUR CHILD AND HOW ARE
YOU DOING?
>> I THINK EVERYONE'S COPING AS
BEST AS THEY POSSIBLY CAN.
IT'S SHOCKING WHEN IT HAPPENS
ANYWHERE.
WE'RE ALL TRYING TO WRAP OUR
ARMS AROUND THE SITUATION AS
BEST AS WE CAN.
>> DOES YOUR DAUGHTER WANT TO
TALK ABOUT IT WITH YOU OR ARE
YOU ENCOURAGING HER TO OR HOW
ARE YOU HANDLING THIS?
A LOT OF PARENTS AROUND THE
WORLD ARE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT TO SAY TO THEIR CHILD.
>> YOU KNOW, THE HARD THING FOR
ME IS I'M A NEW YORKER AND I
GUESS I'M ACCUSTOMED TO
MANHATTAN AND ALWAYS TELLING MY
KIDS TO BE CAREFUL.
I GUESS YOU NEVER EXPECT IT TO
HAPPEN IN YOUR SCHOOL.
AT THE END OF THE DAY, YOU JUST
LET HER TALK.
SHE MENTIONED QUITE A BIT ABOUT
THE PRINCIPAL, WHO MANY OF US
WORKED WITH.
I ADORED HER.
I WORKED WITH HER PERSONALLY
WITH MY BUSINESS.
THAT IS ONE PERSON I KNOW WE
LOST ON A PERSONAL LEVEL.
I KNOW THEY ARE GOING TO HAVE
THE COUNSELLORS AT THE
INTERMEDIARY SCHOOL TODAY.
THEY WERE ALL WELCOME TO GO
THERE.
IF THEY NEED TO SPEAK TO
SOMEBODY, THEY WILL.
>> HAS YOUR DAUGHTER SAID MUCH
ABOUT WHAT SHE SAW OR HEARD?
>> SHE DID MENTION THAT SHE DID
OF COURSE HEAR GUNSHOTS.
THEY WERE ON THE SAME FLOOR.
HER TEACHER MANAGED TO TAKE TWO
CHILDREN OUT OF THE HALLWAY AND
PULL THEM INTO THE CLASSROOM.
LOCK THE DOOR AND MOVE EVERYBODY
OVER TO THE OTHER SIDE OF THE
ROOM.
IT WAS VERY CONFUSING AS IT
WOULD BE IN ANY OF THESE CASES
TO GO AND PICK UP YOUR CHILD
ONCE WE FIGURED OUT THAT
EVERYTHING WAS DISPATCHED TO
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
I WAS ONE OF THE FIRST PARENTS
THERE ALONG WITH A FRIEND OF
MINE.
WE FIGURED OUT WHAT WAS GOING ON
AND I RAN OVER THERE.
THEY WERE SMART TO GET THEM OUT
OF THE BUILDING AND MOVE THEM
OVER TO THE FIREHOUSE.
YOU CAN SEE THAT MY DAUGHTER'S
TEACHER WAS VISIBLY UPSET AS
WELL AS MANY OF THE CHILDREN
THERE.
SHE DID A VERY HEROIC THING AND
PULLED TWO KIDS OUT OF THE HALL
WAY AND SHOVED THEM IN THE CLASS
AND LOCKED THE DOOR.
THE KIDS ARE GOING TO SUFFER
FROM THIS LIKE EVERYTHING ELSE.
IT'S A PSYCHOLOGICAL EVENT THAT
WILL TAKE TIME FOR HEALING.
AS LONG AS EVERYONE GETS THE
PROPER HELP, IT'S NOT SOMETHING
YOU SHAKE OFF EASILY AND NOT FOR
LITTLE PEOPLE.
WE LOST A LOT OF BABIES TODAY IN
THIS TOWN.
THERE A LOT OF VERY SAD
FAMILIES.
AS EVERYONE CAN THINK, YOU NEVER
THINK IT'S GOING TO HAPPEN, BUT
BASICALLY IT HAPPENS ALL OVER
THE WORLD AT THIS POINT.
WE HAVE TO BE COGNIZANT OF
MENTAL HEALTH AND COGNIZANT OF
GUN CONTROL IN MY EYES.
AND ALSO ABOUT HOW SCHOOLS ARE
LOCKED UP THESE DAYS.
IT'S VERY UNFORTUNATE BUT YOU
HAVE TO THINK OF SOMEBODY
BLOWING THEM UP.
IT IS UNFORTUNATE STATE OF
AFFAIRS BUT REALITY THESE DAYS.
>> DENISE, I'M SORRY THAT THAT
REALITY WAS VISITED UPON YOUR
DAUGHTER TODAY AND EVERYBODY
ELSE.
I WISH YOU STRENGTH AND PEACE IN
THE DIFFICULT DAYS AHEAD.
THANK YOU FOR TALKING TONIGHT.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH, ANDERSON.
>> THERE WILL BE A LOT OF
DIFFICULT DAYS AHEAD.
LET'S GO BACK TO SOLEDAD.
>> AS WORD STARTED TO SPREAD
THROUGHOUT THE STATE TODAY,
CERTAINLY SO DID THE SHOCK AND
HORROR AND NOW THERE IS THE
GRIEVING.
>> YOU CAN NEVER BE PREPARED FOR
THIS KIND OF INCIDENT.
WHAT HAS HAPPENED, WHAT HAS
TRANSPIRED AT THAT SCHOOL
BUILDING WILL LEAVE A MARK ON
THIS COMMUNITY AND EVERY FAMILY
IMPACTED.
I ONLY ASK THAT OUR FELLOW
CITIZENS HERE AND AROUND THE
WORLD WHO OFFERED THEIR
ASSISTANCE REMEMBER ALL OF THE
VICTIMS IN THEIR PRAYERS.
>> THAT WAS CONNECTICUT
GOVERNOR'S GOVERNOR MALLOY
SPEAKING EARLIER TODAY.
HE SAID HIS MAIN OBJECTIVE IS
WORKING WITH FEDERAL AND LOCAL
AUTHORITIES.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI HAS BEEN
HANDLING THE COVERAGE OF THE
INVESTIGATION.
LET'S FOCUS ON WHAT WE KNOW
ABOUT THE SHOOTER.
>> NOT VERY MUCH.
THAT HE IS 20 YEARS OLD.
WE UNDERSTAND THAT HE CAME TO
THE SCHOOL WITH THREE WEAPONS.
TWO OF THEM WERE HANDGUNS.
WITH ONE DESCRIBED AS A GLOCK,
ONE DESCRIBED AS A SIG SAUER AND
ANOTHER ONE NOT FOUND IN THE
CLASSROOM WITH HIM BUT IN A CAR
OUTSIDE OF THE SCHOOL THAN IS
CALLED A.223 BUSHMASTER WHICH IS
A SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPON.
IT SEEMS THOSE GUNS WERE NOT
REGISTERED TO HIM, BUT WE ARE
TOLD, ACCORDING TO TOUR LAW
ENFORCEMENT SOURCES THEY BELONG
TO HIS MOTHER, WHICH IS, DON'T
HAVE AN EXPLAN MAGS FOR THAT
RIGHT NOW.
>> ALL OF THOSE GUNS LEGALLY
PURCHASED IN THE STATE.
>> YES.
WE WERE TOLD THEY WERE LEGALLY
PURCHASED AND REGISTERED IN THE
STATE OF CONNECTICUT.
BUT HOW DID HE GET AHOLD THEM WE
DON'T KNOW.
WE BELIEVE HE MIGHT HAVE BEEN
LIVING WITH HIS MOTHER.
I SAY THAT BECAUSE OUR SOURCES
SAY HIS MOTHER'S BODY WAS FOUND
INSIDE OF A RESIDENCES AND SHE
LIVES IN THE AIR.
IT IS POSSIBLE HE LIVED WITH HIS
MOTHER.
STIMWAITI
STILL WAITING FOR THAT DETAIL.
>> POLICE WENT AND TOOK THE
BROTHER FOR QUESTIONING AS WELL.
>> THE BROTHER IS A LITTLE
OLDER, 24 YEARS OLD.
HE LIVES IN AN APARTMENT IN
HOBOKEN.
AUTHORITIES NATURALLY DID GO TO
HIM TO ASK HIM QUESTIONS ABOUT
HIS BROTHER.
EVERYONE IS BEING PRETTY TIGHT
LIPPED ABOUT WHAT HE TOLD THE
AUTHORITIES, BUT ALSO HIS FATHER
HAS BEEN QUESTIONED, AS WELL.
HIS FATHER IS DIVORCED FROM THE
MOTHER WHO WAS KILLED IN THIS
INCIDENT.
AND SO WE ARE SIMPLY TRYING TO
FIND OUT MORE.
>> SUSAN CANDIOTTI, THE
INVESTIGATION CONTINUES.
THANK YOU FOR REPORTING ON THAT,
THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER'S MOTHER.
WE WILL OBVIOUSLY GET MORE
INFORMATION AS WELL.
LET'S GET BACK TO ANDERSON FOR
MORE.
>> YEAH, SOLEDAD, WE ARE
LIMITING THE USE OF THE KILLER'S
NAME.
WE DON'T WANT TO REPIET IT OVER
AND OVER AGAIN.
WE DON'T WANT IT TO GIVE HIM A
HOUSEHOLD NAME AND WE DON'T WANT
TO GIVE ENCOURAGEMENT TO SOMEONE
WHO THINKS THEY CAN SOLVE
SOMETHING THROUGH MURDER.
DREW GRIFFIN IS JOINING ME LIVE.
>> ANDERSON, HAVING COVERED SO
MANY OF THESE IT IS PLAYING OUT
IN A SICKENING ROUTINE, A
SHOOTER WITH POSSIBLE MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES.
A FAMILY TRYING TO DEAL WITH
THOSE ISSUES.
SOMETHING SNAPS.
A GUN IS EASILY ACCESSED AND AN
OUTBURST OF VIOLENCE IN THE CASE
OF THIS 20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER.
IT IS PLAYING OUT EXACTLY IN
THAT ORDER.
HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW.
THE 20-YEAR-OLD HAD AN OLDER
BROTHER.
THAT BROTHER REPORTEDLY TOLD ABC
NEWS THE SHOOTER HAD A
PERSONALITY DISORDER.
HE ALSO MENTIONED AUTISM.
CNN HEARD THAT SAME INFORMATION
FROM A MAN WHO CALLED HIMSELF A
FRIEND OF THE SHOOTERS IN
NEWTOWN WHERE THE SHOOTER LIVED.
WE CAN NOW CONFIRM THE TWO
HANDGUNS AND SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE
WERE, AS SUSAN SAID, LEGALLY
OWNED BY THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER,
NOW LEGALLY DECEASED.
AND IS STANDARD IN THESE CASES
WE FIND PEOPLE THAT ARE SHOCKED
THAT THE PARTICULAR SHOOTER
COULD HAVE BEEN INVOLVED IN
ANYTHING LIKE THIS, AS IS THE
CASE WITH ONE OF THE SHOOTER'S
FORMER CLASSMATES AND FORMER
SCHOOL BUS DRIVER.
LISTEN TO WHAT THEY SAID TODAY.
>> JUST A KID.
>> NEVER ANTI-SOCIAL?
>> NO.
NO.
>> TROUBLEMAKER?
>> NO.
DEFINITELY NOT.
>> NOTICEABLE?
>> DID HE BLEND IN TO THE
BACKGROUND?
YEAH.
NOTHING THAT WOULD WARRANT ANY
OF THIS.
>> THEY ARE SAYING HE WENT AFTER
HIS MOM AND HER CLASS OF KIDS.
CAN YOU WRAP YOUR HEAD AROUND
THAT?
>> NO, I CANNOT.
I DON'T KNOW WHO WOULD DO
ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
>> SO YOUR GENERAL SENSE IS
WHAT?
THIS IS UNSPEAKABLE.
I FIRST HEARD ABOUT IT, I'M
STILL IN SHOCK.
I WANT TO GO.
I NEED TO GO WALK.
>> HE WAS A NICE KID.
VERY POLITE.
SHE RAISED VERIER NICE BOYS TO
ME.
THAT'S WHY I THINK IT IS A SHOCK
TO EVEN KNOW THEM AND REALIZE
WHO THEY ARE.
AND WHAT HE DID.
YOU CAN'T UNDERSTAND WHAT
HAPPENED.
THAT HE SNAPPED, WHAT HAVE YOU
AND HE TOOK SUCH INNOCENT LIVES.
SO WHAT CAN WE EXPECT?
ANDERSON, AS WE LEARNED IN THE
OTHER CASES, VIRGINIA TECH, THE
SHOOTING OF CONGRESSWOMAN
GIFFORDS, THE MASS SHOOTING IN
THE MOVIE THEATER IN COLORADO, I
THINK BY TOMORROW WE WILL SEE IN
HINDSIGHT, MULTIPLE WARNING
SIGNS.
DANGEROUS MESSAGES IGNORED OR AN
OBSESSION WITH THE MOM'S GUNS
THAT WEREN'T TAKEN SERIOUSLY OR
THE FAMILY, IN MANY CASES,
DOESN'T KNOW HOW TO HANDLE THE
SITUATION.
THEY DON'T HAVE ANYWHERE TO
TURN.
THERE WILL NEVER BE AN ANSWER OR
AN EXPLANATION THAT COULD BE
ANYWHERE NEAR GOOD ENOUGH FOR
THE VICTIMS' FAMILIES TO
UNDERSTAND THIS.
A LOT OF CASES IT IS SENSELESS
AND NEVER UNDERSTOOD.
>> YEAH.
IN HEARING ONE OF THE PEOPLE SAW
AUTISTIC, OR COULD BE AUTISTIC,
THAT DOESN'T -- I'VE NEVER HEARD
OF SOMEBODY WHO IS AUTISTIC
DOING SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
>> IT IS TWO SEPARATE THINGS.
THE BROTHER SAID PERSONALITY
DISORDER AND ALSO AUTISTIC.
SO WE'RE NOT TRYING TO PUT THOSE
TOGETHER OR SAYING ONE LEADS TO
THE OTHER BUT THERE WERE SOME
EARLY HINTS, LIKE WE HAVE SEEN
IN OTHER CASES WHERE THERE IS A
MENTAL ISSUE GOING ON AND WE
LEARN MORE AS THINGS GO ON THAT
THERE MAY HAVE BEEN WARNING
SIGNS.
THAT'S WHAT I EXPECT AND SEEN A
LOT OF EXPERTS EXPECT TALKING
ABOUT THIS.
>> THERE'S GOING TO BE A LOT OF
DEBATE OVER GUN ISSUES AND GUN
CONTROL.
CONNECTICUT HAS STRICT GUN LAWS
AND THESE GUNS WERE LEGALLY
PURCHASED AS FAR AS WE KNOW BY
THE MOTHER.
>> YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
IF YOU WERE GOING TO MAKE A GUN
LAW THAT PREVENT YOU WOULD HAVE
TO TAKE THIS WOMAN'S LEGALLY
OWNED GUNS AWAY.
THAT'S BASICALLY IT.
THE REASON WE FOUND OUT SO SOON
WHERE THE GUNS COME FROM,
BECAUSE CONNECTICUT HAS ITS OWN
REGISTRY.
THE HANDGUNS ARE REGISTERED.
YOU HAVE YOU HAVE TO HAVE A
CERTIFICATE TO OWN HANDGUN AND
THAT OWN COMES WITH A TEST, NOT
A TEST BUT A CLASS, A HANDGUN
SAFETY CLASS.
NOBODY UNDER 21 CAN OWN A
HANDGUN AND THEY HAVE AN ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN.
THIS ASSAULT RIFLE, I DON'T HAVE
THE DETAILS BUT IF IT WAS
LEGALLY OWNED SHE MUST HAVE
OWNED IT BEFORE '93 AND ALSO HAD
A CERTIFICATE OF POSSESSION
REGISTERED WITH THE STATE
BECAUSE SOME OLDER GUNS WERE
GRANDFATHERED IN.
YOU CAN'T HAVE AN ASSAULT WEAPON
IN THE STATE OF CONNECTICUT FROM
WHAT I AM A READING FROM THE
GUN.
>> THE OTHER QUESTION IS HOW
WERE THE GUNS STORED.
WERE THEY IN A LOCK BOX WHICH IS
THE RECOMMENDED WAY TO STORE
GUNS.
FOR PARENTS THE ORDEAL BEGAN
WITH WORDS SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
WAS ON A LOCKDOWN.
THAT WAS THE FIRST WORD THAT
PARENTS GOT.
WHEN WE COME BACK, WE WILL HAVE
MORE ON WHAT HAPPENED THROUGHOUT
THE DAY.
U6SH9SDS I 2K3W50E
ASK
TONIGHT OUR GUEST,
THOMAS SARGENT.
NOBEL LAUREATE
IN ECONOMICS,
AND ONE OF THE MOST CITED
ECONOMISTS IN THE WORLD.
PROFESSOR SARGENT,
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT CD RATES WILL
BE IN TWO YEARS?
NO.
IF HE CAN'T, NO ONE CAN.
THAT'S WHY ALLY HAS
A RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
ALLY BANK.
YOUR MONEY NEEDS AN ALLY.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
WITH SCOTTRADER
STREAMING QUOTES,
ANY WAY YOU WANT.
FULLY CUSTOMIZE IT
FOR YOUR TRADING PROCESS --
FROM THOUGHT TO TRADE,
ON EVERY SCREEN.
AND ALL IN REAL TIME.
WHICH MAKES IT JUST LIKE
HAVING YOUR OWN TRADING FLOOR,
RIGHT AT YOUR FINGERTIPS.
[ Rodger ] AT SCOTTRADE,
SEVEN DOLLAR TRADES
ARE JUST THE START.
TRY OUR
EASY-TO-USE
SCOTTRADER
STREAMING QUOTES.
IT'S ANOTHER REASON
MORE INVESTORS ARE SAYING...
[ All ]
I'M WITH SCOTTRADE.
RUSHED HOME.
SHE HEARD SOME BANGS AND SHE WAS
BROUGHT IN TO A BATHROOM.
>> IT WAS FRIGHTENING.
IT WAS LIKE MY HEART STOPPED
BEATING.
IT WAS LIKE -- I CAN'T EVEN
EXPLAIN IT.
>> JASON CARROLL GAVE US A LOOK
INSIDE THE VIGIL MASS.
AND WE ARE JOINED BY THE PASTOR.
APPRECIATE YOU TAKING THE TIME
TO TALK TO US.
HOW DO YOU -- WHAT DO YOU SAY TO
A PARENT?
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO A PARENT
WHOSE GOING THROUGH THE WORST
POSSIBLE GRIEF IMAGINABLE?
>> I HAVE HAD A NUMBER OF
CONVERSATIONS WITH PARENTS A
NUMBER OF THEM BELONG TO THIS
PARISH COMMUNITY.
I MUST SAY THE WORDS ARE FEW.
WHAT CAN YOU REALLY SAY?
MANY OF THEM JUST SAID TO ME
THANK YOU FOR BEING HERE WITH
US.
WE PRAYED TOGETHER.
WE HUGGED EACH OTHER.
THERE WERE A LOT OF TEARS AND
EMOTION AND I DON'T THINK IT
SETTLED IN TO THEIR LIVES THAT
THEIR CHILD HAS BEEN TAKEN FROM
THEM.
I MUST SAY FOR THE PARENTS I
SPOKE WITH TODAY THERE'S A
TREMENDOUS AM OF LOVE FOR THESE
CHILDREN AND I KNOW THE DAYS
AHEAD WILL BE VERY DIFFICULT.
WE AS A COMMUNITY, CERTAINLY AS
A CHURCH COMMUNITY WILL BE
PRESENT TO THEM BUT THE WORDS,
WHAT CAN YOU SAY AT A TIME LIKE
THIS?
>> THERE ARE A LOT OF PARPTS
WRESTLING AROUND THE COUNTRY AND
PROBABLY AROUND THE WORLD WITH
WHAT ARE THEY GOING TO SAY TO
THEIR CHILDREN WHO ASK QUESTIONS
ABOUT THIS.
WHAT WOULD YOU RECOMMEND FOR
PEOPLE TO SAY TO THEIR KIDS, NOT
KIDS FROM NEWTOWN AT THE SCHOOL
BUT WHO HEAR ABOUT THIS AND WANT
TO KNOW ARE THEY SAFE ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED?
>> YOU KNOW, I THINK THAT'S THE
ONE THING YOU HAVE TO ASSURE
THEM ABOUT.
SOME OF THE CIRCUMSTANCES ARE
BEYOND ANY HUMAN CONTROL.
WE HAVE TO TEACH THESE CHILDREN
THAT THEY HAVE TO TRUST.
I KNOW IT IS A DIFFICULT WORLD
IN WHICH WE LIVE AND IT IS VERY
DIFFICULT TO TRUST EVERYONE, BUT
THEY HAVE TO HAVE FAITH AND THEY
HAVE TO HAVE FAITH IN GOD AND
FAITH IN EACH OTHER.
I HOPE THAT THESE PARENTS WILL
CERTAINLY LEARN FROM THIS ONCE
AGAIN THE VALUE OF FAMILY AND
KEEP PRIORITIES VERY STRAIGHT.
THESE CHILDREN NEED TO KNOW THEY
ARE LOVED, THAT THEY ARE IN
ENVIRONMENTS WHERE THEY CAN BE
SAFE AND WHERE THEY CAN GROW UP
TO BE PRODUCTIVE CITIZENS.
I DON'T KNOW HOW YOU TAKE THE
FEAR OUT OF A CHILD'S HEART
EXCEPT BY LOVE.
THESE CHILDREN TODAY WERE DEEPLY
LOVED BY THEIR PARENTS.
I'M SURE WHEN THEY DROP THEM OFF
TO SCHOOL THIS MORNING THE LAST
THING ON THEIR MIND OR THE MINDS
OF THEIR CHILDREN IS THIS WOULD
BE THE WAY THE DAY WILL END.
I HOPE PARENTS WILL TAKE THIS AS
AN OPPORTUNITY TO TALK TO THE
CHILDREN ABOUT THE IMPORTANCE OF
BEING FAMILY AND THE IMPORTANCE
OF TRUSTING AND LOVING EACH
OTHER.
>> ONE OF THE THINGS I WAS
THINKING ABOUT TODAY AFTER THE
AURORA SHOOTING IN AURORA,
COLORADO THEY HAD A MEMORIAL
SERVICE AND I REMEMBER THE
SPEAKERS WOULD READ THE NAME OF
EACH PERSON KILLED.
THE CROWD WOULD SHOUT BACK, WE
WILL REMEMBER YOU.
AND I THOUGHT THAT WAS SO
POWERFUL AND I THOUGHT ABOUT
THAT TODAY.
WE HAVE BEEN TRYING TO EMPHASIZE
THE IMPORTANCE OF REMEMBERING
THE VICTIMS AND I THINK WE SAW
THAT TONIGHT AT THE VIGIL
SERVICE THAT YOU HELD WHERE
PEOPLE WERE OUTSIDE.
SO MANY PEOPLE WANTED TO GO THEY
COULDN'T FIT IN.
WAS YOUR MESSAGE TONIGHT?
>> THE MESSAGE WAS THAT I
THOUGHT THIS WAS A DAY ABOUT
HEARTS.
I WITNESSED THIS MORNING BEING
WITH THE FAMILIES.
I WAS WITH THEM ALMOST SIX
HOURS, COMPASSIONATE, BROKEN
HEARTS, CARING HEARTS AND IT WAS
ABOUT LOVE LOST BUT LOVE NEVER
FORGOTTEN.
I ENCOURAGE OUR PEOPLE TONIGHT
WE HAVE TO DO SOMETHING ABOUT
VIOLENCE IN THIS COUNTRY.
VIOLENCE IN THE MEDIA AND
ENTERTAINMENT INDUSTRY.
IT IS FILLING THEIR HEADS WITH
AN AWARENESS THAT EVIL DOES
EXIST IN THIS WORLD, BUT THAT
GOOD ALWAYS CONQUERS EVIL.
THE ONLY WAY WE WILL CHANGE IS
BY COMING TOGETHER AS A
COMMUNITY.
THAT'S WHAT HAPPENED TONIGHT.
PEOPLE CAME TOGETHER TO SUPPORT
AND ENCOURAGE EACH OTHER AND TO
LET EACH OTHER KNOW THERE IS A
BETTER WAY TO LIVE.
WE DON'T HAVE TO BE AFRAID IF WE
WORK TOGETHER AS A COMMUNITY.
>> I KNOW IT HAS BEEN A LONG DAY
FOR YOU AND A HORRIFIC DAY FOR
YOU.
APPRECIATE YOU TAKING THE TIME
TO TALK TO US.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> YEAH.
AND AGAIN, SOLEDAD AS WE HAVE
BEEN SAYING ALL DAY LONG THERE
ARE MANY DIFFICULT DAYS AHEAD.
>> NO QUESTION.
FOR THOSE WHO LOST CHILDREN AND
THOSE WHOSE CHILDREN SURVIVED
THOSE TOUGH CONVERSATIONS.
MANY PARENTS WERE TELLING US
WHAT HAPPENED WHEN THEY CAME
RACING TO THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
OVER HI SHOULDER.
THEY GOT THE WORD THAT THE
SCHOOL WAS ON LOCKDOWN AND THEY
WERE PANICKED.
SOME TRIED TO RUN TO THE SCHOOL.
THEY WERE SENT TO A NEARBY FIRE
STATION, FRANTIC SCENE BY ALL
ACCOUNTS THAT WE HAVE HEARD AS
PEOPLE HAD TO SIT THERE AND WAIT
TO SEE IF THEIR CHILDREN WERE
ALIVE OR NOT.
EARLIER, I SPOKE WITH CHRISTINE
WOFFORD ABOUT HER EXPERIENCE.
HER SON IS A SECOND GRADER AT
THE SCHOOL.
HOW ARE YOU DOING NOW?
>> IT'S STILL, STILL PROCESSING.
IT'S SCARY, SCARY.
NO WORDS.
>> TELL US HOW YOUR SON IS
DOING.
ARE YOU ENCOURAGING HIM TO TALK
AND SHARE OR ARE YOU TRYING TO
TAKE HIS MIND OFF OF THE
TERRIBLE THINGS HE WITNESSED AND
EXPERIENCED?
>> WE HAVE DEAN LITTLE BIT -- W
HAVE DONE A LITTLE BIT OF EACH.
TRYING TO SPOIL HIM LET HIM PLAY
THE PS-3 AND LETTING HIM KNOW
WHEN WE FOUND OUT ABOUT OTHER
CHILDREN THAT HE KNOWS.
>> YOU HAVE GOTTEN AN ELECTRONIC
ALERT IS HOW YOU GOT THE MESSAGE
IN A ROBOCALL.
CAN YOU DESCRIBE WHAT WAS SAID
AND IT MUST HAVE BEEN THE MOST
TERRIFYING THING.
>> MY HUSBAND AND I WAS SITTING
THIS AND A NEIGHBOR WAS OVER AND
WE GOT A ROBO CALL THAT ALL THE
SCHOOLS WERE IN LOCKDOWN DUE TO
A SHOOTING.
AND WE IMMEDIATELY GOT ON-LINE
AND MY NEIGHBOR SAID HER HUSBAND
SAID IT WAS SANDY HOOK AND WE
HOPPED IN THE CAR AND HEADED TO
THE SCHOOL.
>> THE SCHOOL WAS ON LOCKDOWN,
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
>> I'M NOT SURE EXACTLY WHAT
THAT MEANS.
WHEN I GOT THERE, ALL OF THE
CHILDREN THAT HAD BEN VAC WAITED
WERE IN THE FIRE HOUSE, VERY
CLOSE BY.
>> HOW IS YOUR SON DOING AND HOW
ARE THE KIDS HE WAS WITH HOLDING
UP?
IT.
>> VARIED.
MY SON SEEMED TO BE OKAY.
HE'S LIKE MOM, I'M OKAY.
I'M SAFE.
GAVE MAE BIG HUG.
A LOT OF CHILDREN WERE CRYING
AND SCARED.
>> WHAT DID HE DESCRIBE THAT
HAPPENED?
>> HE SAID HE HEARD WHAT SOUNDED
LIKE LARGE PANS FALLING.
JUST LOUD NOISES.
HE SAID HE TEACHER STEPPED
OUTSIDE OF THE CLASSROOM AND
IMMEDIATELY CAME IN AND LOCKED
THE DOOR AND HAD THEM GET IN A
CORNER AND SIT DOWN AND HAD THEM
TO START READING QUIETLY.
>> HOW MUCH TIME WENT BY BETWEEN
THAT HAPPENING AND BEFORE HE WAS
ABLE TO GET TO YOU?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
HE ISN'T ABLE TO PIECE HOW MUCH
TIME PASSED.
HE SAID AFTER A LITTLE WHILE A
POLICE OFFICER CAME AND TOOK
THEM OUT OF THE BUILDING AND
BROUGHT THEM TO THE FIRE HOUSE.
>> WE KNOW THE PRINCIPAL HAD
INSTALLED A SYSTEM WHERE YOU
HAVE TO BE BUZZED IN.
>> YES.
IT'S BEEN THAT WAY FOR THE TWO
YEARS THAT WE HAVE BEEN HERE.
YOU HAD TO BUZZ -- YOU HAVE TO
RING A DOORBELL TO BE LET IN.
THE OFFICE IS RIGHT IN FRONT OF
THOSE DOORS.
SO THEY CAN LOOK OUT AND SEE
WHO'S AT THE DOOR.
>> ANY REASON FOR THAT?
IT IS TYPICAL IN BIG CITIES
CERTAINLY, BUT IN COMMUNITIES
THAT ARE PRETTY RURAL, IT'S A
LITTLE BIT OF A RARITY
SOMETIMES.
>> I THINK IT IS JUST, THEY TAKE
THE SAFETY OF OUR CHILDREN VERY
SERIOUS.
IT'S A FAIRLY LARGE SCHOOL.
THERE'S BETWEEN 500 AND 600
STUDENTS THERE.
THEY WANT TO KEEP CONTROL AND
KNOW WHO'S IN THE BUILDING WITH
OUR CHILDREN.
>> I WAS TALKING TO THE STATE
POLICE AND THEY SAID THAT THEY
ARE PROCESSING THE SCENE STILL
WHICH MEANS THERE ARE STILL SOME
CHILDREN INSIDE.
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN TO YOUR SON
WHAT HAS HAPPENED ABOUT HIS
CLASSMATES?
>> WE ARE A FAIRLY RELIGIOUS
FAMILY AND WE HAVE TALKED ABOUT
THEY HAVE GONE TO HEAVEN TO BE
WITH JESUS AND THAT'S ABOUT ALL
WE CAN SAY.
TALK ABOUT YOU ARE NOT GOING TO
SEE THEM ANYMORE AND THEY ARE
NOT GOING TO BE AROUND.
YOU REALLY STRUGGLE TO FIND THE
WORDS, YOU KNOW, AS TO WHAT
HAPPENED.
>> YOU SHOULD KNOW THAT EVERYONE
IS SENDING WELL WISHES NOT JUST
TO YOU AND YOUR FAMILY BUT YOUR
COMMUNITY AS A WHOLE.
SO MANY PEOPLE HAVE ASKED ME TO
PASS THAT ALONG.
>> WE'RE A STRONG COMMUNITY, A
STRONG FAMILY COMMUNITY WITH A
LOT OF LOVE.
I THINK THAT WE WILL GET THROUGH
THIS SOMEHOW, SOME WAY.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
WE APPRECIATE IT.
BACK TO ANDERSON.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WE WILL BE RIGHT BACK.
OH, HEY MIKE.
WHAT ARE YOU UP TO?
OH, JUST DIAGRAMMING
THIS ACCIDENT
WITH MY State Farm
POCKET AGENT APP.
YOU CAN ALSO GET A QUOTE AND PAY
YOUR PREMIUM WITH THIS THING.
I THOUGHT State Farm
DIDN'T HAVE ALL THOSE APPS?
WHERE DID YOU HEAR THAT?
THE INTERNET.
AND YOU BELIEVED IT?
YEAH. THEY CAN'T PUT ANYTHING ON
THE INTERNET THAT ISN'T TRUE.
WHERE DID YOU HEAR THAT?
[ Both ] THE INTERNET.
OH LOOK.
HERE COMES MY DATE.
I MET HIM ON THE INTERNET.
HE'S A FRENCH MODEL.
UH, BONJOUR.
[ Male Announcer ]
State Farm.
MORE MOBILE THAN EVER.
GET TO A BETTER STATE.
Bye!
Santa, we made a video for
your trip!
Yeah, you can watch it on your
sleigh!
OK!
Here you go.
Aw, thanks elves.
I also made you a video.
You are so sweet.
But you probably shouldn't watch
it on the sleigh.
Say goodbye to Santa boys!
Bye!
Good bye Santa!
Share videos instantly
with S Beam on the
Galaxy S3 and Note 2.
Available at Best Buy and
Best Buy mobile stores.
>>> YOU HEARD THE MONSIGNOR
WEITZ TALKING ABOUT THE BROKEN,
LOVING HEARTS.
HE SPOKE OF HEALING THOSE
HEARTS.
HERE'S MORE FROM THE VIGIL
TODAY.
>> I WOULD LIKE TO SHARE A
LETTER FROM HIS HOLINESS, POPE
BENEDICT XVI.
I WAS INFORMED OF THE SHOOTING
AT HANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
I CONVEY MY HEART FELT AND
PRAYERS TO THE VICTIMS AND
FAMILIES.
TO ALL OF THOSE IN THE COMMUNITY
OF NEWTOWN AND ESPECIALLY THE
PARISH OF ST. ROSE OF LIMA.
>> I HAVE NO WORDS THAT MAKE THE
PAIN OF WHAT HAPPENED TODAY EASY
TO BEAR.
I AM HEARTBROKEN AS I KNOW ALL
OF YOU ARE.
THERE IS NOTHING MORE HURTFUL
AND TRAGIC THAN THE LOSS OF
INNOCENCE, BUT NO MORE SO WHEN