ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WILL BE ON THE
WALLS THERE.
THEIR DESKS WILL BE IN PLACE
THERE.
AND THERE'S EVEN REPORTEDLY
PHOTOGRAPHS THAT WERE TAKEN AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY OF WHAT
THE CLASSROOMS LOOKED LIKE SO
THE PROFESSIONAL MOVERS COULD
MOVE EVERYTHING IN AND MAKE IT
LOOK EXACTLY THE SAME WAS
REALLY, TRULY A REMARKABLE FEAT
GIVEN THE DURESS EVERYONE'S
UNDER.
TRUCKS HAVE BEEN COMING UP AND
DOWN DELIVERING ALL OF THE
EQUIPMENT, DESKS AND JUST ALL OF
THE GEAR THAT YOU NEED TO
ACTUALLY FUNCTIONALLY MAKE A
SCHOOL HAPPEN FOR LITTLE
CHILDREN.
>>> A SHATTERED TOWN TRIES TO
RETURN TO SOME SENSE OF EVERYDAY
LIFE, KNOWING THAT NOTHING IS
REALLY EVER GOING TO BE THE
SAME.
MOST STUDENTS IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT RETURN TO CLASS
TODAY BUT NOT THOSE AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY.
THERE'S A FUNERAL HELD FOR
ANOTHER CHILD TODAY, KILLED IN
THAT MASSACRE.
I'M SUZANNE MALVEAUX IN ATLANTA.
>> AND I'M ASHLEIGH BANFIELD,
LIVE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THIS IS NEWSROOM'S SPECIAL
COVERAGE, "NEWTOWN REMEMBERS."
TODAY, GRIEVING FAMILIES ARE
SAYING GOOD-BYE TO A 6-YEAR-OLD
GIRL WHILE YESTERDAY TWO LITTLE
BOYS WERE LAID TO REST.
CONNECTICUT'S GOVERNOR HAS NOW
TAKEN ON THE ROLE OF COMFORTER,
AS THE HEARTBREAKING SCENE PLAYS
OUT TOO MANY TIMES.
>> THE GOVERNOR'S ASKING PEOPLE
ACROSS CONNECTICUT TO PAUSE FOR
A MOMENT OF SILENCE FRIDAY AT
THE
SHOOTING THAT KILLED THOSE 20
CHILDREN AND 6 ADULTS AT THE
SCHOOL.
HE SENT A MESSAGE TO GOVERNORS
AROUND THE COUNTRY ASKING THEIR
STATES TO DO THE SAME.
WE WANT TO UPDATE YOU ON NEW
DEVELOPMENTS IN THE AFTERMATH OF
THE TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN.
SCHOOLS REOPEN TODAY FOR THE
FIRST TIME SINCE THE SHOOTING
RAM PAGE.
MORE POLICE, EXTRA COUNSELORS OF
COURSE ON HAND.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY STILL
REMAINS CLOSED.
FUNERAL SERVICES ARE BEING HELD
FOR ANOTHER 6-YEAR-OLD.
JESSICA REKOS LOVED HORSES AND
EXPECTING A NEW PAIR OF COWGIRL
BOODS FOR CHRISTMAS.
FAMILY MEMBERS ARE TRYING TO
HELP HER BROTHER UNDERSTAND WHY
HE CAN'T PLAY WITH HIS BEST
FRIEND.
A FORMER DIRECTOR OF SECURITY
FOR NEWTOWN SCHOOLS IS SHEDDING
NEW LIGHT ON THE GUNMAN.
HE WAS ASSIGNED TO KEEP TRACK OF
STUDENTS HAVING PROBLEMS,
INCLUDING ADAM LANZA BUT SAYS HE
NEVER THOUGHT OF LANZA AS A
THREAT.
ASHLEIGH, TELL US ABOUT THE
EMOTION THAT YOU ARE SEEING.
OBVIOUSLY, A LOT OF PEOPLE WHO
ARE -- THEY ARE BURYING THEIR
DEAD.
AT SAME TIME, TRYING TO MOVE ON
AND GIVE THEIR OTHER CHILDREN A
SENSE OF HOPE IN THIS COMMUNITY.
>> ONE OF THE THINGS I'VE BEEN
NOTICING SURROUNDING
COMMUNITIES, PEOPLE FROM
SURROUNDING COMMUNITIES HAVE
BEEN COMING HERE TO PAY THEIR
RESPECTS, JUST TO BE A PART OF
IT SOMEHOW, SHOW THEY ARE WITH
THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN AND THEY
SUPPORT THEM IN THEIR GRIEF.
IT'S ALMOST UNBELIEVABLE THE
NUMBER OF PEOPLE WITH TEARS IN
THEIR EYES JUST WALKING DOWN THE
STREET.
YOU CAN'T WALK ANYWHERE NEAR I
AM WITHOUT ENCOUNTERING SOMEONE
WITH A CHILD OR TWO ADULTS
WALKING HAND IN HAND, CRYING,
BECAUSE THEY'VE JUST DROPPED OFF
FLAGS OR TEDDY BEARS OR CANDLES
OR ORIGAMI OR SOME CHRISTMAS
ORNAMENT WITH THE NAME OF A
CHILD.
WE ALL KNOW IT'S OKAY TO BE
WALKING DONE STREET CRYING.
EVERYONE SEEMS TO UNDERSTAND.
THAT'S WHAT THIS IS ALL.
AND I JUST WANT TO LET YOU KNOW
ALSO, THERE'S A CAFE I'VE BEEN
FREQUENTING AND WORKING IN, AND
I WENT UP TO BUY A COMPANYl)r O
COFFEE AND THE WOMAN SELLING IT
SAID IT'S FREE OF CHARGE.
SOMEONE CALLED THIS MORNING AND
SAID, THEY WANT TO PAY FOR
EVERYONE WHO COMES IN TO THE
CAFE TODAY AS A GESTURE OF LOVE.
THAT HAPPENED A SECOND TIME.
A SECOND CALLER ANONYMOUSLY
OFFERED TO PAY FOR EVERYONE'S
COFFEE COMING IN.
THAT'S THE KIND OF THING
HAPPENING HERE.
EVERYBODY FEELS LIKE THEY'RE IN
THE SAME BOAT AND IT'S A
TERRIBLE BOTH TO BE IN.
AT THE SAME TEAM THERE'S AN
INVESTIGATION AND FORMAL AND
SERIOUS AND MASSIVE.
THE INVESTIGATION INTO WHY AND
HOW ADAM LANZA DID WHAT HE DID
ON FRIDAY AND CHANGED THIS
COMMUNITY AND COUNTRY FOREVER.
DEBORAH FEYERICK IS FOLLOWING
THAT PART OF THE INVESTIGATION.
SHE'S LIVE AS WELL.
WHAT'S THE NEW INFORMATION THAT
YOU ARE GETTING?
SPECIFICALLY FROM THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER?
>> Reporter:
>> Reporter: JUST A COUPLE OF
MINUTES AGO, ANOTHER
INVESTIGATOR DROVE UP THE LONG
DRIVEWAY TO GET BACK INTO THE
THOUSAND SEARCH FOR MORE
EVIDENCE.
BUT THE MEDICAL EXAMINER, H.
COSBY, TOXICOLOGY TESTS WERE
DONE ON ADAM LANZA.
THEY'RE TRYING TO DETERMINE THE
KIND OF MEDICATIONS THAT HE MAY
HAVE BEEN ON AND THE EFFECTS OF
THOSE MEDICATIONS ALSO FOR THE
FIRST TIME, OFFICIALLY, THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER SAYING THAT
ADAM LANZA DID HAVE AS BERGER'S
BUT THAT'S WHAT HE'S BEING TOLD
BUT TAKING IT ONE STEP FURTHER
TO FIND OUT IF THAT WAS THE
CORRECT DIAGNOSIS, WHETHER OR
NOT THERE WAS MORE GOING ON
INSIDE THIS YOUNG MAN.
THE BODIES OF THE MOM AND THE
ALLEGED GUNMAN, ADAM LANZA, BOTH
OF THEM, HAVE UNDERGONE
AUTOPSIES.
THEY HAVE NOT BEEN RELEASED.
NOBODY HAS CLAIMED BODIES YET.
NOBODY WILL BE NOTIFIED WHEN
THEY ARE UNTIL AFTER THE
BURIALS.
THAT IS AT THE REQUEST OF THE
FAMILY.
A COUPLE MORE GRUESOME DETAILS
COMING OUT ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
INSIDE THIS HOME ON FRIDAY
MORNING.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER SAYING,
ACCORDING TO THE AUTOPSY REPORT,
NANCY LANZA WAS SHOT IN THE HEAD
FOUR TIMES AS SHE SLEPT IN HER
PAJAMAS IN HER BED.
THE DEATH OF THE ALLEGED GUN
MAN, HE DIED BY A SINGLE SHOT,
ALSO TO THE HEAD.
NOW, THE DIVORCE DOCUMENT, THIS
SORT OF TAKING IT TO THE NEXT
STAGE, LOOK AT DIVORCE DOCUMENT,
YOU'RE TRYING TO SEE WAS IT JUST
SOME KIND OF DIAGNOSIS OF
ASPERGERS OR SOMETHING ELSE
GOING ON.
ACCORDING TO THE DIVORCE
DOCUMENT, NANCY LANZA WAS
RESPONSIBLE FOR PAYING ALL
UNREIMBURSED PSYCHIATRIC AND
PSYCHOLOGICAL EXPENSES, ALSO SHE
WAS RESPONSIBLE FOR PICKING UP
THE COST OF PRESCRIPTION
MEDICATIONS.
SO WHEN IT CAME TO HER SON'S
MENTAL HEALTH IT APPEARS SHE
REALLY WAS IN CHARGE OF MAKING
SURE THAT HE WAS GETTING THE
RIGHT KIND OF HELP AND
MEDICATIONS.
THAT'S ACCORDING TO THE DIVORCE
DOCUMENH5H
HARD TO MAINSTREAM
HER SON EVEN THOUGH HE DIDN'T
FIT IN, THOUGH AS A FRESHMAN
HERE IN NEWTOWN, YOU KNOW, HE
WAS GIVEN A SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST
AND SCHOOL SAFETY OFFICERS
WATCHED HIM CAREFULLY BECAUSE HE
WAS SO AWKWARD, SO GAWKY, OUT OF
PLACE, AND ANTI-SOCIAL THEY WERE
AFRAID THAT HE WOULD BECOME THE
VICTIM OF SOME SORT OF CRIME,
LIKE BULLYING.
IN FACT, THAT DIDN'T HAPPEN.
WE CAN'T GET AWAY FROM THE FACT,
ASHLEY, THAT THIS IS A KID WHO
JUST FELL OFF THE GRID.
ABOUT THREE YEARS AGO, NO
RECORDS OF WHAT HE'S BEEN DOING
SINCE 2009 WHEN THE LAST RECORD
SHOWS THAT HE WAS TAKING CLASSES
AT A LOCAL UNIVERSITY, CLASSES
LIKE COMPUTER SCIENCE AND MACRO
ECONOMICS AND AMERICAN HISTORY.
HE'S DESCRIBED AS A GENIUS.
BUT WHATEVER HAPPENED IN THE
LAST THREE YEARS, BOY, SOMETHING
WENT TERRIBLY WRONG, ASHLEIGH.
>> DEB, IT'S HAUNTING TO SEE
THAT PHOTOGRAPH THAT SHOWS ADAM
LANZA AT HIS MOST RECENT STATE
IN LIFE BEFORE THIS HAPPENED.
DEB FEYERICK REPORTING FOR US
OUTSIDE THE LANZA HOME.
>>> WE ARE ALL TRYING TO MAKE
SENSE OF HOW THIS HAPPENED, ALL
TRYING TO MAKE SENSE OF THOSE
EYES, OF THIS STORY, THIS
TRAGEDY.
HOW THIS COULD HAPPEN ANYWHERE,
LET ALONE THE TINY TOWN.
INVESTIGATORS TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT WHAT WAS GOING THROUGH HIS
MIND.
ONE OF THE PEOPLE WHO MAYBE ABLE
TO OFFER SOME INSIGHT IS ALLEN
DIAZ, FORMER CLASSMATE OF ADAM
LANZA WHO SPOKE EXCLUSIVELY TO
CNN'S NATIONAL CORRESPONDENT,
SUSAN CANDIOTTI.
>> Reporter: AMONG THE STEADY
STREAM OF PEOPLE DRAWN TO THE
MEMORIAL HONORING VICTIMS, A
FORMER SCHOOLMATE OF THE ALLEGED
KILLER.
>> WHAT DO YOU THINK OF THIS?
DOES YOUR MIND GO TO YOUR
FRIEND?
>> OBVIOUSLY, IT DOES BECAUSE
YOU KNOW, HE'S A VERY BIG PART
IN THIS EVENT.
I'M NOT REALLY SURE WHAT TO
THINK OF IT.
>> Reporter: SADLY, HE'S THE
REASON FOR IT?
>> YEAH.
>> Reporter: ALLEN DIAZ MAY HAVE
BEEN AS CLOSE AS ANYONE WHO
COULD COME TO BEING A FRIEND OF
ADAM LANZA WHEN HE WAS A
SOPHOMORE AT NEWTON SCHOOL, AND
DIAZ WAS A FRESHMAN IN 2008.
>> VERY INTELLIGENT PERSON.
HE REALLY WAS.
IT'S LIKE THE WAY HE ACTED
AROUND OTHER PEOPLE WAS JUST
REWITHDRAWN AND REALLY QUIET.
>> Reporter: A LITTLE DIFFERENT?
>> YEAH.
>> Reporter: THEY WERE IN THE
HIGH SCHOOL TECH CLUB TOGETHER,
SPENT A LOT OF TIME ON
COMPUTERS.
ADAM HAD HIS OWN STYLE OF
DRESSING.
>> KIND OF HAD LIKE THE STEEFR
STEREOTYPICAL NERD LOOK, KHAKI
PANTS, BELT, TUCKED-IN SHIRT.
EVEN COMPUTER m)
BRIEFCASE, INSTEAD OF LIKE A
BACKPACK LIKE EVERYONE ELSE.
HE EVEN HAD A POCKET PROTECTOR
THAT HE HAD PENS IN.
>> Reporter: HE DOESN'T KNOW
WHETHER LANZA WAS BULLIED.
HE KEPT TO HIMSELF.
>> WE ALL KIND OF KNEW THAT LIKE
HE HAD PROBLEMS SOCIALLY AND WE
KIND OF HAD A FEELING THAT THERE
MIGHT HAVE BEEN SOMETHING WRONG
WITH HIM BUT OBVIOUSLY WE NEVER
ASKED, THOUGHT IT WAS OUR PLACE
TO DO SO.
>> Reporter: BACK THEN HIS
SCHOOLMATE'S MOM ONCE INVITED
ALL OF HIS FRIENDS TO THE HOUSE
TO PLAY VIDEO GAMES.
ONE WAS STARCRAFT, A WAR GAMES
IN SPACE.
ANOTHER WAS WAR CRAFT 3 WHEREAS
THE AD SAYS, SURVIVAL IS A
MATTER OF STRATEGY.
>> THE BURNING SHADOW COMES TO
CONSUME US ALL.
>> WAR CRAFT 3 WAS FUN.
HE WAS REAL FLY GAMES AND HE
PICKED UP ON STAR CRAFT QUICKLY.
>> WHEN LANZA LEFT HIGH SCHOOL
AND HOME SCHOOLED, DIAZ LOST
TOUCH BUT RAN INTO LANZA'S
MOTHER NANCY ABOUT TWO YEARS
AGO.
>> I REMEMBER HER LIKE
MENTIONING THAT HE STARTED GOING
TO THE SHOOTING RANGE WITH HER.
MY INITIAL RESPONSE TO THAT WAS,
I NEVER IMAGINED ADAM ONE TO
EVER EVEN HOLD A GUN.
>> Reporter: WHY DO YOU SAY
THAT?
>> I DON'T KNOW, MAYBE BECAUSE
IN MY MIND I DON'T IMAGINE SHY,
QUIET PEOPLE GOING TO A SHOOTING
RANGE.
I NEVER REALLY CAN MAKE THAT
ASSOCIATION.
>> Reporter: INVESTIGATORS HAVE
R. TRACKING HOW OFTEN LANZA HAD
BEEN TO GUN RANGES.
THEY DON'T KNOW HOW MANY SO FAR.
THEY'VE PROVEN HE'S BEEN TO
TARGET PRACTICE SIX MONTHS AGO,
AND FOR SEVERAL YEARS.
MOTHER AND SON WENT AT LEAST
ONCE TOGETHER.
ALLEN'S OLDER SISTER WENT TO
SCHOOL WITH THE SHOOTER'S OLDER
BROTHER.
AND SHE WAS FRIENDS WITH THEIR
MOTHER WHO WENT TO HER BRIDAL
SHOWER LAST YEAR.
>> WHY HER?
SHE WAS JUST -- I CAN'T.
IT WAS A SHOCK.
SHE ALWAYS A HAPPY, HAPPY
PERSON.
>> Reporter: DO YOU NOW THINK OF
HIM AS AN EVIL PERSON?
BECAUSE OF WHAT HE DID?
>> ONE POINT HE WAS A GOOD KID.
THE EVENT THAT WILL HE DID THAT
DAY MAY HAVE BEEN EVIL BUT
BEFORE THEN, HE -- HE WAS JUST
ANOTHER KID.
>> Reporter: UNTIL SOMETHING
MADE HIM SNAP.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI, CNN, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> A LOT OF OPINIONS, OP-EDS
WRITTEN IN THE AFTERMATH OF THE
TRAGEDY.
MAN SUPPORT MORE GUN CONTROL AS
WELL AS MENTAL HEALTH SERVICES.
OTHERS THINK THERE SHOULD BE
MORE GUNS AS A MEANS OF PROTECT
THEMSELVES.
DAVID GERGEN WHO HAS WRITTEN A
OP-ED IN CNN.COM.
SOMEONE WHO HAS ADVISED FOUR
PRESIDENTS, YOU SAY CLEARLY WE
NEED A CHANGE IN OUR CULTURE,
THE CULTURE OF GUNS AND GUN
POLICY.
AND YOU SAY THAT IN ORDER TO
HONOR THE DEAD, YOU'VE GOT TO
HAVE SOME KIND OF ACTION.
WHAT IS THE MOST IMPORTANT THING
RIGHT NOW FOR THE PRESIDENT TO
DO?
>> SEIZE THE MOMENT.
THE OPINION IN THE COUNTRY NOW
jf GUN
SAFETY.
WE HAVE HAD MAJORITIES AND TWO
POLLS, CBS, "THE WASHINGTON
POST"/ABC SAYING WE NEED
STRICTER LAWS, STRICTER EARN
FORCEMENT, AND THAT'S -- THAT'S
PRETTY BIG SHIFT.
AS YOU KNOW, OPINION HAD BEEN
SHIFTING AWAY TOWARD MORE PEOPLE
HAVING GUNS AND THE WHOLE IDEA
OF A WAY TO SOLVE THIS PROBLEM,
IF EVERYBODY HAS A GUN YOU CAN
STOP THE SHOOTER.
OF COURSE THAT DOUBLES DOWN ON
THE PROBLEM AND WE HAVE A
CULTURE IN WHICH GUNS ARE MORE
AVAILABLE TO YOUNG PEOPLE AND
THAT APPROACH.
>> THE PRESIDENT CAN'T DO IT
ALONE.
HE NEEDS COOPERATION OF
CONGRESS.
THREE BASIC PRINCIPLES SHOULD
GUIDE OUR GUN POLICIES.
FIRST YOU HAVE TO -- MUST HAVE A
LICENSE TO OWN A GUN.
THE LICENSE SHOULD NOT BE EASY
TO GET.
SO HOW DIFFICULT SHOULD IT BE
WHAT WOULD BE YOUR PARAMETERS?
>> I THINK THE PERMIT SYSTEM NOW
IS FULL OF HOLES.
IT'S DETERMINED AT THE STATE
LEVEL.
WE HAVE VERY UNEVEN LAWS.
AS YOU KNOW, SUZANNE, YOU CAN --
THE PERMIT SYSTEM AS A
BACKGROUND CHECK, A WAITING
PEER, THAT'S ALL VERY HELPFUL.
IT DONE GET INTO WHETHER YOU
KNOW HOW TO USE A GUN.
THE KINDS OF THINGS WE DO TO
LICENSE PEOPLE TO DRIVE.
CARS ARE DANGEROUS BUT WE LET
PEOPLE DRIVE AFTER THEY GET A
LICENSE, ONCE THEY PROVE TO US
THEY KNOW HOW TO HANDLE IT.
THE SAME THING SHOULD BE TRUE OF
GUNS.
WE SHOULD HAVE A STRICT
LICENSURE APPROACH SO WE KNOW
WHO HAS THE GUN AND YOU CAN MAKE
ADJUSTMENTS.
WITH MODERN TECHNOLOGY YOU COULD
PUT IN EFFECT A PASSWORD ON A
GUN SO SOMEONE -- IF SOMEONE
PICKS UP YOUR iPAD, THEY DON'T
KNOW YOUR PASSWORD THEY CAN'T
GET INTO YOUR iPAD THE SAME IS
TRUE OF GUNS.
IF YOU PUT A PASSWORD ON A GUN,
SOMEONE LIKE ADAM DIDN'T HAVE
THE PASSWORD HE WOULDN'T HAVE
BEEN ABLE TO USE IT.
YOU -- IF YOU LICENSE THE MOTHER
AND THEN MADE SURE THAT HE
DIDN'T HAVE ACCESS, WE MIGHT NOT
HAVE HAD ALL OF THESE DEAD KIDS.
>> SECOND, IF YOU'RE A CIVILIAN
COW CAN'T BUY AN ASSAULT GUN.
FOLKS SAY I'M A HUNTER, I WANT
TO PROTECT MY HOME AND I WANT A
WEAPON HERE.
PEOPLE TEODAY FURIOUS, DICK'S
SPORTING GOODS NOT SELLING THESE
ACROSS THE COUNTRIER.
TWEETS COMING OUT.
THIS MAKE ME NOT WANT TO SHOP AT
DICKS.
OTHERS SAYING I CALLED DICKS TO
CANCEL MY REWARDS ZONE
MEMBERSHIP.
TOLD THE GUY ON THE PHONE IF I
RECEIVE ANOTHER PIECE OF
LITERATURE IN THE MAIL FROM THEM
I WILL SUE THEM.
HOW DO YOU RESPOND TO THOSE
PEOPLE WITH THAT ANGER WHO FEEL
THEY SHOULD BE PERMITTED TO HAVE
THOSE WEAPONS?
>> YOU AND I HAVE BEEN AROUND
ENOUGH ON THE INTERNET TO KNOW
IF JESUS CHRIST APPEARED AND
GAVE ANOTHER SERMON ON THE MOUNT
SOME PEOPLE WOULD ATTACK.
AND EXPRESS FURY ABOUT SOME
ASPECT OF IT.
YOU KNOW, YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
THAT.
THERE'S GOING TO BE NOISE IN THE
SYSTEM.
THE QUESTION FOR POLITICAL
FIGURES, THE NATION, WHAT'S THE
MORALLY RIGHT ANYTHING TO DO?
IF WE DON'T ACT NOW, GIVEN WHAT
WE KNOW ABOUT THE DEATHS OF
THESE CHILDREN, WE ENABLE THE
NEXT PERSON TO COME ALONG, THE
NEXT LONER MENTALLY DER RANGED
TO COME ALONG, SHOOT A BUNCH OF
KIDS WE'LL HAVE BLOOD ON OUR OWN
HANDS.
WE'LL HAVE MORAL RESPONSIBILITY.
WE'LL BE ENABLERS IF WE DON'T
ABILITY.
I THINK THE MOMENT'S HERE.
I UNDERSTAND THE POLITICS OF IT.
I KNOW THE POLITICS ARE ROUGH.
DEMOCRATS FELL WHEN THEY PASSED
AN ASSAULT BAN IN 1994 WHEN.
CLINTON WAS PRESIDENT, THEY FELT
THEY LOST THE HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES IN LARGE PART
BECAUSE OF THAT AND THEY'VE BEEN
NERVOUS ABOUT IT EVER SINCE.
IT'S ABOUT SEIZING THE MOMENT
WHEN IT'S THERE AND MOVING AS TO
A DIFFERENT WAY TO LIVE.
I THINK YOU FIND -- MY ARGUMENT
ON CNN.COM WAS, YOU HAVE TO FIND
MEANING IN TERRIBLE HORRORS LIKE
THIS.
AND WHAT WE LEARNED FROM
LINCOLN, WHEN HE WENT ON THE
GETTYSBURG ADDRESS HE DIDN'T
TALK ABOUT THE PEOPLE IN THE
BATTLEFIELD.
WORDS ARE TOO LITTLE.
WE HAVE TO GIVE NEW MEANING TO
NATIONAL LIFE.
THAT'S THE LEADERSHIP WE NEED.
>> WE'LL SEE IF THEY'VE GOT THE
POLITICAL COURAGE TO DO THAT IN
THIS ADMINISTRATION.
THANK YOU.
>> COURAGE AS A RIGHT WORD.
THANKS, SUZANNE.
>> ASHLEIGH?
>> IT'S SO INTERESTING TO HEAR
YOU AND DAVID GERGEN HAVING THAT
CONVERSATION OVER THE GUN
CONTROL DEBATE.
THERE'S ANOTHER BIG CONVERSATION
REIGNITING NOW AND THE DEBATE
OVER VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES AND
WHETHER THEY LEAD TO ACTUAL
VIOLENCE.
IF YOU'RE A PARENT AND THIS
PLAGUES YOU, YOU ARE CONCERNED
ABOUT, WE'VE GOT ADVICE COMING
UP IN A MOMENT.
>> MEDIA VIOLENCE IS A RISK
FACTOR, IS A CAUSAL RISK FACTOR
FOR INCREASED AGGRESSIVE
BEHAVIOR.
[ Female Announcer ]
WHAT IF THE NEXT BIG THING,
ISN'T A THING AT ALL?
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
CONNECTING
TO THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
>>> 14 DAYS AND KOUPTSING TO THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
BOEHNER LETTING TAXES INCREASE
ON $1 MILLION A YEAR, A PLAN B,
SHORT-TERM STEP TO AVOIDSdyñ MAE
SPENDING CUTS AND TAX HIKES THAT
WOULD AFFECT EVERY AMERICAN
STARTING JANUARY 1st.
LISTEN.
>> EVERY INCOME TAX FILER IN
AMERICA'S GOING TO PAY A HIGHER
RATE JANUARY 1st, UNLESS
CONGRESS ABILITIY OCTOBERS.
I BELIEVE IT'S IMPORTANT THAT WE
PROTECT AS MANY AMERICAN
TAXPAYERS AS WE CAN.
AND OUR PLAN B WOULD PROTECT
AMERICAN TAXPAYERS WHO MAKE $1
MILLION OR LESS AND ARE ALL OF
THEIR CURRENT RATES EXTENDED.
>> WANT TO BRING IN OUR WHITE
HOUSE CORRESPONDENT DAN LOTHIAN.
WE KNOW THAT THE PRESIDENT SAYS,
LOOK, CAMPAIGNED ON THOSE
EARNING MORE THAN $250,000 WOULD
NOT SEE A TAX INCREASE.
NOW IT'S BEEN RAISES TO ABOUT I
BELIEVE $400,000.
WHERE ARE WE IN THE NEGOTIATIONS
HERE?
>> Reporter: THAT'S WHERE IT
STANDS.
I THINK IT WAS THE DRAMATIC
DEVELOPMENT OVERNIGHT WHEN THE
PRESIDENT DID SHIFT FROM
SOMETHING HE HAD BEEN PUSHING
OUT ON THE CAMPAIGN TRAIL AND
THE LAST FEW WEEKS SAYING
ESSENTIALLY NO DEAL COULD GET
DONE IF TAXES DID NOTTEN CREASE
ON THOSE HOUSEHOLDS MAKING MORE
THAN $250,000.
NOW THE PRESIDENT RAISING THAT
TO $400,000.
I THINK THERE WAS A LEVEL OF
OPTIMISM HERE IN WASHINGTON THAT
THIS DEAL COULD GET DONE SOON.
NOW, YOU HAVE SPEAKER
INCUMBENTINCUMBEN
INCUMBENTINCUMBENBOEHNER
WITH PLAN B, TO AVOID SOME OF
THE EFFECTS OF THE SO-CALLED
FISCAL CLIFF.
SECRETARY -- PRESS SECRETARY
HERE JAY CARNEY PUTTING OUT A
STATEMENT A SHORT TIME AGO
SAYING, QUOTE, THE PARAMETERS OF
A DEAL ARE CLEAR AND THE
PRESIDENT'S WILLING TO WORK TO
REACH A BIPARTISAN SOLUTION THAT
AVERTS THE FIRST, PROTECTS
MIDDLE CLASS, HELPS THE ECONOMY
AND PUTS OUR NATION ON A
FISCALLY SUSTAINABLE PATH BUT
NOT WILLING TO ACCEPT A DEAL
THAT DOESN'T ASK ENOUGH OF THE
VERY WEALTHIEST IN TAXES AND
INSTEAD SHIFTS THE BURDEN TO THE
MIDDLE CLASS AND SENIORS.
THE SPEAKER'S PLAN B APPROACH
DOESN'T MEET THIS TEST.
AND IT REALLY HAS BEEN A BACK
AND FORTH BECAUSE WE SOON HEARD
BACK FROM SPEAKER BOEHNER'S
OFFICE, BRAN DAN BUCKS SAYING,
THE WHITE HOUSE'S POSITION
DEFIES COMMON SENSE.
WHAT IS CLEAR, THOUGH, THAT IS
BOTH SIDES HERE, DESPITE THE
BACK AND FORTH IN THE PLAN B,
BOTH SIDES SAY THAT THEY'RE
WILLING TO SIT DOWN AND WORK ON
AN AGREEMENT, THIS BROADER
AGREEMENT BUT A LOT OF CONCERN
AS THE CLOCK TICKS DOWN.
>> LOOKS LIKE BOTH SIDES SEEM TO
BE GIVING IN A LITTLE BIT,
GIVING UP SOMETHING.
DOES THIS LOOK LIKE A POLITICAL
TACTIC, THE FACT HE'S GOING TO
SAY THERE'S A PLAN B?
THAT IT REALLY DOES POSITION
BOEHNER TO GO BACK TO HIS BASE
AND SAY, LOOK, WE TRIED, GAVE IT
OUR BEST EFFORT AND BOTH SIDES
CAN COME OUT AND SAVE FACE?
>> Reporter: WELL, CERTAINLY,
SPEAKER BOEHNER'S LOOKING TO PUT
PRESSURE ON THE WHITE HOUSE.
SPEAKER INCUMBENTER, AS HE GOES
BACK TO HOUSE REPUBLICANS TRYING
TO GIVE THEM SOMETHING TO BUY
INTO, ESSENTIALLY, THIS
PROPOSAL, AND ONE OF THE THINGS
THAT HE CAN DO IS SAY, LOOK, THE
PRESIDENT HAS COME OFF THIS
$250,000 CAP ESSENTIALLY THAT HE
HAD -- THAT HE HELD SO 15 FAST
FOR SO LONG AND THAT'S WHAT HE'S
DOING IN SELLING THIS TO
REPUBLICANS.
WHILE IT APPEARED THE DEAR WAS
CLOSE, AND IT STILL MAY BE, A
LOT OF TALKS ARE GOING ON BEHIND
THE SCENES, THIS IS ANOTHER
ç%sáQ'CH IN THE DEBATE.
>>> PEOPLE REMEMBERING DANIEL
INOUE, HE DIED YESTERDAY OF
RESPIRATORY COMPLICATIONS IN
WASHINGTON, D.C.
A WORLD WAR II VETERAN WHO
RECEIVED THE MEDAL OF HONOR
ONSECUTIVE
TERMS, THE LONGEST SERVING
MEMBER OF THE SENATE.
ALSO A MEMBER OF THE WATERGATE
COMMITTEE THAT RESULTED IN THE
RESIGNATION OF PRESIDENT NIXON.
HE WAS JUST 88.
>>> WHO OWNS RIGHTS TO ALL OF
THOSE PICTURES THAT YOU'RE
POSTING ON PHOTO SHARING
WEBSITES?
IF YOU POST YOUR PHOTOS ON
INSTAGRAM THE COMPANY SAYS IT
DOES.
SO A CHANGE TO THE COMPANY'S
PRIVATE POLICY BASICALLY SAYS,
THAT YOUR PERSONAL PICTURES CAN
NOW BE USED IN ONLINE ADS.
YOU DON'T GET A TIME.
INSTAGRAM INSISTS YOU OWN THE
ACTUAL PICTURES BUT IT IS TAKING
THE COMMERCIAL RIGHTS STARTING
JANUARY 16th.
ALMOST 100 MILLION PEOPLE ARE
USING THIS PHOTO SHARING
SERVICE.
>>> SUZANNE, AS WE'RE REPORTING,
THE NEWS HAS COME IN THAT FIVE
OF OUR COLLEAGUES IN THE MEDIA,
AMERICAN MEDIA, FROM NBC, WERE
HELD CAPTIVE IN SYRIA AND IN AN
INCREDIBLE ESCAPE WERE ABLE TO
BREAK FREE FROM THEIR CAPTORS
AFTER FIVE DAYS OF BEING HELD
AND BLINDFOLDED.
WE'LL BRING YOU THEIR STORY
AFTER THE BREAK.
[ Male Announcer ]
RED LOBSTER'S CRABFEST
ENDS SOON.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OUR TENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
YOU CAN STAY IN
AND LIKE SOMETHING...
OR YOU CAN GET OUT THERE
AND ACTUALLY LIKE SOMETHING.
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
>>> KIDNAPPED, BLINDFOLDED,
THREATENED FOR FIVE DAYS.
AMERICAN JOURNALIST LIVES TO
TELL THAT STORY.
RICHARD ENGEL AND HIS CREW WERE
CAPTURED LAST THURSDAY AFTER
CROSSING INTO NORTHWEST SYRIA
FROM TURKEY.
THEY SUFFERED PSYCHOLOGICAL
TORTURE.
>> THEY TOOK US TO A SERIES OF
SAFE HOUSES AND INTERROGATION
PLACES, AND THEY KEPT US
BLINDFOLDED, BOUND, WE WEREN'T
PHYSICALLY BEATEN OR TORTURED.
IT WAS A LOT OF PSYCHOLOGICAL
TORTURE, THREATS OF BEING
KILLED.
THEY MADE US CHOOSE WHICH ONE OF
US WOULD BE SHOT FIRST.
WHEN WE REFUSED THERE WERE MOCK
SHOOTINGS.
THEY PRETENDED TO SHOOT GAZI,
WHEN YOU'RE BLINDFOLDED AND THEY
FIRE THE GUN UP IN THE AIR IT
CAN BE A TRAUMATIC EXPERIENCE.
AT THE END OF THIS, WE WERE
BEING MOVED TO YET ANOTHER
LOCATION IN THE -- AROUND 11:00
LAST NIGHT LOCAL TIME, AND AS WE
WERE MOVING ALONG THE ROAD, THE
KIDNAPPERS CAME ACROSS A REBEL
CHECK POINT SOMETHING HE HADN'T
EXPECTED.
WE WERE IN THE BACK OF WHAT YOU
THINK OF AS A MINIVAN.
AS WE WERE DRIVING ALONG THE
ROAD, THE KIDNAPPERS SAW THIS
CHECKPOINT, STARTED A GUNFIGHT
WITH IT, TWO OF THE KIDNAPPERS
WERE KILLED.
WE CLIMBED OUT OF THE VEHICLE
AND THE REBELS TOOK US.
WE SPENT THE NIGHT WITH THEM.
WE DIDN'T GET MUCH SLEEP.
HOLMES.
YOU KNOW RICHARD, YOU KNOW HIM
WELL.
FIRST OF ALL, IT'S SUCH A RELIEF
TO SEE THAT HE IS OKAY.
BUT TELL US WHAT KIND OF
JOURNALIST HE IS, WHAT HE'S
EXPERIENCING BECAUSE I KNOW YOU
HAVE -- YOU'VE FACED A LOT OF
SITUATIONS SIMILAR IN IRAQ AND
AFGHANISTAN.
>> YEAH.
HE'S A GOOD GUY.
WE BUMP INTO EACH OTHER LIKE ALL
SORT OF WAR CORRESPONDENT CLUB
IF YOU LIKE, HAVE BUMPED INTO
HIM IN AFGHANISTAN, IN IRAQ ON
MULTIPLE OCCASION.
HE'S ONE OF THE GUYS SEEN AS
FEARLESS, GETS IN THERE GETS HIS
HANDS DIRTY, GETS IN AMONGST THE
WEEDS.
THIS SORT OF THING, SADLY CAN
HAPPEN.
WE'VE HAD OUR OWN PEOPLE IN
SYRIA.
IT'S ONE OF THOSE THINGS.
IF YOU GET STOPPED ABOUT A
RANDOM GROUP AND KIDNAPPED.
ALL OF MY TIME IN IRAQ, 13 TIME
I WAS MORE WORRIED ABOUT KIDNAP
THAN ROADSIDE BOMBS AND
FIREFIGHTS WITH THE MILITARY
BECAUSE THEY INVARIABLY DID NOT
END WELL.
THIS WAS, IN A WAY, THEY WERE
LUCKY.
IF THEY HAD BEEN KIDNAPPED BAY
HARD LINE JIHADIST GROUP THAT
MAY HAVE ENDED BADLY FOR THEM,
TOO.
THEY WERE LUCKY IN THAT THEY
WERE KEPT ALIKE, THEY HIT THE
ROADBLOCK AND DURING THAT
FIREFIGHT THEY WEREN'T SOMEHOW
HIT.
AN EXTRAORDINARY TIME OF ESCAPE,
AND LUCK.
>> TELL US ABOUT THE
PREPARATION.
WHEN YOU GO INTO A WAR ZONE, YOU
AND I BOTH HAVE TAKEN CLASSES,
FIVE DAYS OF WAR SCHOOL WHERE
THEY GAME OUT SCENARIOS.
YOU KNOW YOU HAVE A GAME PLAN
BEFORE YOU GO IN.
>> YEAH.
HOSTILE ENVIRONMENT TRAINING.
THAT COVERS A BUNCH OF THINGS
FROM BATTLEFIELD, MEDICAL
TREATMENT TO ARMAMENTS AND ALSO
KIDNAPPING.
AND BASICALLY TO GIVE
JOURNALISTS A FEEL, A SENSE OF
WHAT IT WOULD BE LIKE.
YOU GET A PREPARATION.
BUT NOTHING WILL PREPARE YOU FOR
THE REAL THING.
YOU CAN DO ALL OF THE PREP YOU
LIKE BUT WENT THAT HAPPENS, YOU
CAN PREPARE BUT YOU CAN'T
PREPARE.
THAT WOULD HAVE BEEN AN
ABSOLUTELY TERRIFYING INCIDENT
THINKING THEY WERE GOING TO BE
KILLED, MOCK EXECUTIONS.
THEY ARE HAVE TO DECOMPRESS.
I IMAGINE IF I WERE THEM -- WHEN
WE WERE AMBUSHED IN 2004 AND PLY
TRANSLATOR AND DRIVE WHERE
KILLED IN THE ATTACK AND
CAMERAMAN SHOT IN THE HELD, AND
THAT WAS A HORRIBLE EXPERIENCE,
WE STAYED TOGETHER FOR THE NEXT
FIVE DAYS AND TALKED IT OUT
AMONGST OURSELVES.
THE WORST THEY COULD DO IS GO
HOME, SEPARATE WAYS AND ALL OF
THAT, STICK IT OUT, HAVE A CHAT,
AND DECOMPRESS.
>> HOW DID YOU GET THROUGH THAT?
>> WITH THE GUYS.
TALKING IT THROUGH WITH THEM AND
OUR SECURITY GUY WITH US THAT
DAY AND BASICALLY SAVED OUR
LIVES.
WE DEBRIEFED EXTENSIVELY.
WE MOURNED.
YOU KNOW YOU MOURN THOSE THAT
YOU LOST.
AND YOU SORT OF THEN MOVE ON.
BUT IT'S ALWAYS WITH YOU.
THE ANNIVERSARY'S JANUARY 27, I
REMEMBER IT LIKE IT WAS
YESTERDAY.
HAPPENED IN 2004.
RICHARD'S SEEN A LOT OF STUFF IN
HIS CAREER.
SOMETHING DIFFERENT, AS IT WAS
WITH THE AMBUSH, CERTAINLY FOR
ME, IT WAS PERSONAL.
I HAD BEEN IN A BUNCH OF
FIREFIGHT.
THESE GUYS WERE TRYING TO KILL
US, THAT'S A PERSONAL THING.
THESE GUYS WERE KIDNAPPING THEM
AND THEY DIDN'T KNOW WHAT WAS
HAPPENING.
IT'S DIFFERENT TO BEING AN
OBSERVER.
THEY'RE GOING TO HAVE TO WORK
THROUGH SOME OF THIS.
I'M GLAD THAT THEY'RE OKAY.
IT WAS WORRYING WHEN WE KNEW
THEY WERE MISSING.
>> WHAT GAVE YOU THE STRENGTH TO
GO BACK OUT THERE AFTER YOU
EXPERIENCED SO MUCH AND SEEING
YOUR COLLEAGUES GUNNED DOWN?
>> FOR ME PERSONALLY.
>> YES.
>> IT WAS RESPECT FOR OUR LOCAL
STAFF.
I DIDN'T WANT TO BE THE
WESTERNER WHO SOMETHING BAD
HAPPENED AND I RAN AWAY.
I WAS BACK IN SIX MONTHS BECAUSE
I WANTED TO GO BACK AND A SIGN
OF RESPECT AND SOLIDARITY.
THAT'S JUST FOR ME.
EVERYBODY'S DIFFERENT.
EVERYBODY DEALS WITH THESE
THINGS DIFFERENTLY, TOO.
SOME PEOPLE CAN HANDLE IT bZOwR
THAN OTHERS AND IT'S A FACTOR OF
HOW YOU'RE WIRED.
ONE'S NOT GOOD OR BAD, WHETHER
YOU CAN HAND IT OR NOT.
IT'S JUST HOW YOU'RE WIRED.
I WENT BACK ANOTHER EIGHT OR
NINE TIMES BECAUSE I CARED ABOUT
THE STORY.
AND I WANTED TO GO BACK TO SEE
OUR GUYS AGAIN, RELATIVES AND
FRIENDS OF THOSE KILLED.
>> HOW DID YOUR FAMILY DEAL WITH
THAT?
THEY --
>> ANNOYED.
>> -- ANGRY TO GO BACK THERE.
>> THAT'S PROBABLY WHY I'M
DIVORCEDED.
MY DAUGHTER, AFTER THAT
INCIDENT, SHE USED TO HATE ME
GOING BACK THERE.
BUT SHE REALIZED WHAT WE DO.
AND YOU KNOW YOU HAVE A PASSION
TO TELL THE STORY.
AND MANY WAYS IT'S A PRIVILEGE
TO GO SO SOME OF THE PLACES AND
TELL THE STORY, IT'S AN AN OR.
THE RISKS ARE THERE.
I TELL YOUNG JOURNALISTS, IT'S
NOT FUN.
AND SHOOT-UPS AND FIREFIGHTS AND
THE RISK OF KIDNAPPING IT'S NOT
A VIDEO GAME, AND PEOPLE DIE.
AND SO IT'S NOT SOME GLORIOUS
ADVENTURE.
IF YOU CARE ABOUT THE STORY, YOU
ARE DRAWN BACK TO IT.
AND ALSO AGAIN, AS I SAY, FOR ME
I NEEDED TO GET BACK TO THE
BAGHDAD BUREAU TO SEE OUR STAFF.
WE HAD A BIG IRAQI STAFF.
>> GLAD YOU'RE OKAY.
WE RESPECT WHAT YOU DO.
WE ARE RELIEVED THAT RICHARD
ENGEL IS ALSO OKAY, HE AND HIS
CREW.
>> THANK YOU.
>> IRAQ'S TALABANI IS
HOSPITALIZED AND IN BAGHDAD.
THE 79-YEAR-OLD LEADER SUFFERED
A STROKE AND HIS HEALTH
CONDITION IS NOT GOOD.
BUT THE PRESIDENT'S OFFICE HAS
NOT CONFIRMED THAT YET.
THE OFFICIAL LINE THAT IS HE HAS
HAD A HEALTH EMERGENCY.
MR. TALABANI ELECTED PRESIDENT
IN 2005.
HE'S LEFT THE COUNTRY SEVERAL
TIMES FOR MEDICAL ISSUES.
WANT TO GO BACK TO ASHLEIGH IN
CONNECTICUT FOR THE OTHER BIG
STORY WE ARE FOLLOWING.
>> AS YOU DRIVE THROUGH OR WALK
THROUGH THIS TOWN, YOU SEE
CHURCHES EVERYWHERE.
THERE ARE A LOT OF PEOPLE OF
FAITH IN THIS TOWN.
AND THEIR FAITH HAS
UNQUESTIONABLY BEEN SHAKEN.
HOW ON EARTH DO YOU ANSWER THE
QUESTION, HOW CAN GOD LET
SOMETHING LIKE THIS HAPPEN?
GOING TO TALK TO A MAN OF FAITH
ABOUT DEALING WITH THAT VERY
QUESTION AND THE QUESTION OF
EVING RAINING DOWN UPON NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, IN A MOMENT.
>>> IN THE WAKE OF THE TRAGEDY
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IN CONNECTICUT, MANY IN THE
COMMUNITY HAVE BEEN COMING
TOGETHER AND THEY ARE RELYING ON
THEIR FAITH TO GET THROUGH
REALLY DARK DAYS.
I WANT TO TALK ABOUT THE ROLE OF
FAITH.
BISHOP ROBERT WRIGHT OF THE
EPISCOPAL DEOIOCESE OF ATLANTA.
YOU WERE ORPHANED, WENT TO
HOWARD UNIVERSITY, MAJORED IN
POLITICAL SCIENCE AND HISTORY,
YOU WERE IN THE NAVY SEARCH AND
RESCUE.
YOU HAVE A BROAD LIFE
EXPERIENCE.
PEOPLE LOOK AT THIS TRAGEDY AND
THEY ASK AND WONDER, HOW DOES
SOMETHING LIKE THIS HAPPEN?
HOW DO YOU HAVE FAITH?
HOW DOES GOD FIGURE INTO ANY OF
THIS?
>> SURE.
YOU KNOW, I MEAN FIRST THING WE
SAY, OF COURSE, IS THAT OUR
HEARTS AND PRAYERS ARE WITH
THOSE WHO ARE IN THE MIDST OF
THIS TRAGIC, TRAGIC SEASON.
WE CAN'T BEGIN TO PUT ALL OF THE
WORDS NECESSARY AROUND THIS.
WE JUST SIMPLY LET PEOPLE KNOW
THAT, AS THE PRESIDENT SAID,
YOU'RE NOT ALONE IN THIS.
WE WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT OUR
PRAYERS AND GOODWILL ARE
FLOODING INTO YOU.
AND INTANGIBLE, WAYS.
BUT AT SAME TIME REAL FAITH
ACCOUNTS FOR HUMAN TRAGEDY AND
HUMAN LOSS AND GRIEF.
A REAL GOD CAN HELP US IN A REAL
WORLD.
AND I THINK THAT IN SOME OF THE
WAYS WE'VE HEARD THE
CONVERSATION FRAMED IT DOESN'T
REALLY ADEQUATELY GET TO THAT.
WE BELIEVE, AT LEAST IN THE
CHRISTIAN TRADITION, THAT GOD
FINDS US AMIDST BRUTALITY,
VIOLENCE.
IS THAT RESOURCE IN THE MID OF
THAT?
THE FACT THAT TRAGEDY HAS
VISITED UNITED STATES IS NOT
EVIDENCE OF THE ABSENCE OF GOD.
I THINK, AND I'M SURE WE'LL SEE
AS DAYS UNFOLD, THERE WILL BE
WONDERFUL EXPRESSIONS OF GRACE
IN THE MIDST OF TRAGEát IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
PEOPLE FROM LOT OF DIFFERENT
BACK GROUNDS ARE SUPPORTING ONE
ANOTHER AND THAT'S THE BEST OF
FAITH.
>> HOW DO YOU APPROACH PEOPLE
WHO THINK IT'S A TIME THAT HAS
TESTED THEY'RE FAITH AND
CHALLENGED THEIR FAITH, AND
MAYBE THEY ARE LOSING FAITH
BECAUSE THEY FEEL AN
OVERWHELMING SENSE OF GRIEF?
>> SURE.
I WOULD SAY TO THEM, I WOULD
LISTEN TO THEM AND I THINK THAT
THOSE FEELINGS ARE LEGITIMATE,
BUT I WOULD GUIDE THEM AND HELP
THEM TO UNDERSTAND THAT THE BEST
PART OF OUR TRADITION ENLARGES
AND DEEPENS OUR FAITH IN THE
MIDST OF THESE OCCURRENCES.
WE TALK ABOUT THE CROSS IN
CHRISTIANITY.
THE CROSS HELPS US TO UNDERSTAND
GOD IS WITH US AMIDST SORRY AND
I THINK THAT AS WE GO DEEPER IN
OUR FAITH, WE WILL FIND GRACE IN
THE MIDST OF THIS.
>> I WANT TO PLAY THIS CLIP.
THIS IS THE HUSBAND OF DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG, PRINCIPAL AT THE
SCHOOL WHO WAS KILLED.
>> SURE.
>> I'M NOT ANGRY ANYMORE.
I'M NOT ANGRY.
I'M NOT ANGRY ANYMORE.
I'M JUST VERY SAD.
>> HE'S NOT ANGRY ANYMORE, HE'S
JUST VERY, VERY SAD.
WHERE DOES THE ROLE OF
FORGIVENESS PLAY IN THIS?
HOW IMPORTANT IS THAT?
IS THAT SOMETHING'S GOING TO
TACK A LONG TIME?
>> THIS IS THE GIT THAT FAITH
GIVES US.
ALLOWS US PROCESS COMPLICATED
MOTIONS LIKE HURT AND ALLOWS US
AND GUIDES US TOWARDS
FORGIVENESS.
WE DON'T FORGIVE OTHERS FOR
THEM.
WE USE FORGIVENESS SO WE MIGHT
BE SET FREE.
GOD SHOWS US GOD'S GRACE TOWARDS
US AND WE PLAY THAT BACK IN OUR
LIVES AND WITH OUR LIVE -- IN
OUR LIVES WITH OTHER.
WE NEED FORGIVE BUT IT'S A
PROCESS AND IT TAKES TIME AND
IT'S ABOUT PRAYER AND IT'S ABOUT
THE STUDY OF GOOD'S GOODNESS
TOWARDS US IN THE MIDST OF OUR
OWN ABSENCE OF GRACE TOWARDS
OTHERS WE FIND THAT WE'VE BEEN
FORGIVEN.
0 WE MIR THAT BACK IN THE WORLD.
THIS IS A PROCESS.
AND I WOULD SAY THAT ONE OF THE
THINGS THAT WE'VE GOT TO DO,
WE'VE GOT TO FORGIVE ADAM LANZA.
WE GOT FIND IT WITHIN OUR HEARTS
TO FORGIVE HIM.
HE WAS A BROKEN YOUNG MAN FROM
WHAT WE CAN TELL RIGHT NOW.
AND WE HAVE GOT TO FIND IT
WITHIN THE BEST OF OUR FAITH
TRADITION TO FORGIVE HIM AND
MOVE FORWARD.
>> FOR THOSE WHO DON'T BELIEVE
IN THE FAITH, THEY DON'T BELIEVE
IN HEAVEN OR BELIEVE THERE'S A
BETTER PLACE FOR A 6-YEAR-OLD TO
BE EXCEPT IN THEIR ARMS, WHAT DO
YOU SAY TO THOSE FOLKS WHO DON'T
BELIEVE IN GOD OR HAVE THAT
FAITH?
>> I THINK THAT WE CAN GO SO FAR
AND JUST IN OUR CAPACITY TO LOVE
AND TO BE WITH ONE ANOTHER.
WE CAN GO SO FAR.
BY I THINK WHEN WE GET INTO
PROCESSING COMPLEX EMOTIONS LEAK
THE NEED FOR FORGIVENESS, WE
LACK THE STRENGTH TO TAKES US
THE FULL WAY OF OURSELVES, THIS
IS WHERE FAITH IS A RESOURCE TO
US.
IT MOVES US BEYOND OURSELVES.
IT ENLARGES OUR HEARTS.
IT STIRS UP RESERVOIRS OF
COMPASSION IN US.
AND THAT'S WHAT I WOULD SAY.
WE NEED TO DRAW DOWN ON THAT.
>> ALL RIGHT.
BISHOP WRIGHT, THANK YOU FOR
YOUR WORDS AND ENCOURAGEMENT.
A LOT OF PEOPLE LISTENING AND A
LOT OF PEOPLE NEED THAT.
>> WE'LL TAKE A QUICK BREAK AND
WE'LL HAVE MORE.GI
VEME RATES FOR
PROGRESSIVE DIRECT AND OTHER
CAR INSURANCE COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
>>> WHEN 20 CHILDREN ARE GUNNED
DOWN IN THEIR ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
AND SIX GROWN-UPS ARE GUNNED
DOWNEN IN AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
AND A WOMAN IS MURDERED IN HER
OWN BED BY HER OWN SON WHO
PERPETRATED THAT CRIME THERE IS
NO TEMPLATE FOR HOW A TOWN LIKE
THIS COPES.
THERE IS NO TEMPLATE FOR WHAT
BECOMES THEIR REALITY.
I WANTED TO JUST DO SOMETHING
FOR YOU AND SHOW YOU WHAT IT IS
LIKE TO ARRIVE IN THIS TOWN NOW
THAT THE ENTIRE WORLD IS
WATCHING THEM.
TAKE A LOOK.
ONE OF THE FIRST THINGS YOU'LL
NOTICE AS YOU DRIVE INTO THIS
BEAUTIFUL TOWN OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, SOME OF THE OLD
BUILDINGS AND THE LOVELY, GENTLY
ROLLING HILLSIDE AND THIS
EXTRAORDINARY TRAFFIC.
THE SCHOOL BUSS ARE NOW ROLLING
ONCE AGAIN AS THESE KIDS GET
READY TO HEAD BACK TO SCHOOL IN
THE NEWTOWN DISTRICT TODAY.
IT IS NOT NORMALLY LIKE THIS.
THE TRAFFIC IS COMPRISED OF
PEOPLE FROM SURROUNDING
COUNTIES, CONTRACTORS COME IN TO
HELP WITH THIS EMERGENCY, MAYBE
REBUILDING IN SOME OF THE
SCHOOLS, ET CETERA.
AND THEN ALSO AN ENORMOUS NUMBER
OF MEDIA.
ANOTHER THING YOU NOTICE, AS YOU
COME INTO TOWN, RIGHT AWAY ON
THE LEFT-HAND SIDE IS THIS
MAKESHIFT MEMORIAL THAT SPRUNG
UP SEVERAL DAYS AGO AND IS
GROWING EXPONENTIALLY, PEOPLE
BRINGING TEDDY BEARS, CANDLES,
ARTWORK AND MESSAGES AND OR GAM
MI AND FLOWERS, YOU NAME IT,
JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING.
YOU SEE A LOT OF PEOPLE WITH
TEARS AS THEY DROP OFF WHAT THEY
BROUGHT.
OBVIOUSLY SOME OF THE TRAFFIC
WITH PEOPLE FROM SURROUNDING
COMMUNITIES.
NEXT THING YOU NOTICE IS THIS.
ALL OF THE MEDIA.
PEOPLE HAVE COME FROM ALL OVER
THE WORLD TO COVER THIS STORY
AND THEY ARE SET UP RIGHT IN THE
TOWN SQUARE.
RIGHT IN THE CENTER OF TOWN.
A PLACE THAT IS NOT USED TO
SEEING SATELLITE TRUCKS AND THIS
KIND OF MEDIA ATTENTION.
BOY, ARE THEY GETTING USED TO IT
NOW.
ANOTHER THING THAT YOU'LL FIND
AMIDST ALL OF THE TRAFFIC, TAKE
A LOOK UP HERE.
POLICE AND ORANGE CONES AND ROAD
CLOSED SIGNS, THAT IS THE ROAD
THAT LEADS UP TO THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THEY'RE OBVIOUSLY LIMITING MOST
OF THE TRAFFIC, NOT ALLOWED TO
GO UP THERE AT THIS TIME.
THAT'S THE OTHER AREA WHERE
THERE'S A MASSIVE, MASSIVE
MEMORIAL.
I SHOWED THAT TO YOU YESTERDAY.
BUT ONE OF THE THINGS THAT WE DO
HERE FROM PEOPLE, WHILE
EVERYBODY AROUND THE COUNTRY AND
AROUND THE WORLD WANTS TO SHARE
AND WANTS TO KNOW AND WANTS TO
BE A PART OF THIS GRIEVING, AND
THEY'RE DOING THAT THROUGH US
AND THE WINDOW WE PROVIDE THE
PEOPLE WHO LIVE HERE WOULD LIKE
US TO LEAVE.
THEY WANT TO RETURN SOME
NORMALCY AND THAT BEGS THAT
QUESTION, WHEN WE DO GO, WHEN WE
LEAVE THIS TOWN AND WHEN OUR
WORLD CONTINUES, WE LEAVE ALL OF
THESE PEOPLE WITH A BRAND-NEW
NORMAL AND SOMETHING THEY'RE
GOING TO HAVE TO FIGURE OUT FOR
THEMSELVES WHAT THEIR NEW NORMAL
IS GOING TO BE LIKE.
AND I JUST WANT TO SHARE AN
ANECDOTE.
MOMENTS AGO A MAN BY THE NAME OF
JOE WHALEN CAME HERE TO MEET ME
BY THE CREEK AND SEEN THE PIECE
RUN TODAY ON CNN.
HE LIVES IN TOWN NOT FAR AWAY.
HE'S A GENERAL CONTRACT, BUILDS
HOMES IN THE COMMUNITY.
HE WAS SO MOVED BY THAT NOTION
THAT ONCE WE ALL LEAVE, THEY
WILL BE LEFT ALONE WITH THEIR
NEW NORMAL.
HE DIDN'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
HE SAID I WANT TO DO SOMETHING.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
AND ULTIMATELY HE CAME UP WITH A
PLAN AND HE SHARED IT WITH ME
MOMENTS AGO.
HE'S GOING TO GO AROUND TOWN TO
ALL OF THOSE AFFECTED BY THE
TRAGEDY AND WITH SOME OF HIS
COLLEAGUES IN THE BUILDING
BUSINESS, HE'S GOING REPAIR
THEIR HOMES.
WHATEVER HE SEES NEEDS DOING
HE'S GOING TO DO IT AND HE'S NOT
GOING TO ASK FOR ANYTHING IN
RETURN.
A SMALL EXAMPLE OF HOW THE
COMMUNITY PLANS TO BIND TOGETHER
TO TRY TO GET THROUGH THIS AS A
UNIT.
I WAS VERY THANKFUL THAT HE
SHARED THAT WITH ME.
WE ARE ALL GRIEVING THROUGH THIS
TERRIBLE TRAGEDY, THE MEDIA
INCLUDED.
AND NOW MORE THAN A MILLION
PEOPLE, A MILLION PEOPLE, HAVE
SIGNED AN ONLINE SYMPATHY CARD
FOR THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WE'LL HAVE MORE ON THAT IN A
MOMENT.
[ Female Announcer ]
WHAT IF THE NEXT BIG THING,
ISN'T A THING AT ALL?
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
CONNECTING
TO THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
TOMATO,
OBVIOUSLY.
HAHA. THERE'S MORE
THAN THAT THOUGH,
THERE'S A KICK TO IT.
WAHLALALALALLALA!
SMOOTH, BUT CRISP.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE DRINKING
A FOOD THAT'S A DRINK,
OR A DRINK THAT'S A FOOD,
WOOOOOH!
[ Male Announcer ] TASTE IT
AND DESCRIBE THE INDESCRIBABLE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
♪ HARK HOW THE BELLS,
SWEET SILVER BELLS ♪
♪ ALL SEEM TO SAY
THROW CARE AWAY ♪
♪ FROM EVERYWHERE,
FILLING THE AIR ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
CHEX PARTY MIX.
EASY 15-MINUTE
HOMEMADE RECIPES
YOU JUST POP IN A MICROWAVE.
LIKE CARAMEL CHOCOLATE
DRIZZLES.
HAPPIER HOLIDAYS.
CHEX PARTY MIX.
>>> THE OUTPOURING OF SYMPATHY
AND SUPPORT FOR VICTIMS OF THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTING SETS
AN ONLINE RECORD.
MORE THAN 1 MILLION SPEPEOPLE
SIGNED THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL ONLINE SYMPATHY CARD.
LARGEST PETITION EVER ON THE
THE FOUNDER OF 9/11 DAY STARTED
THE E-CARD FOR PEOPLE TO EXPRESS
SORROW OVER THE SHOOTING.
THE CARD WAS RECEIVING MORE THAN
1,000 SIGNATURES PER MINUTE.
A LOT OF SUPPORT THERE.
>> BEYOND THE DEBATES OVER GUN
CONTROL AND THE DISCUSSIONS OVER
MENTAL ILLNESS, THERE'S ANOTHER
BIG DISCUSSION THAT HAS COME UP
AS WELL AND IT'S THE QUESTION
OVER THE POSSIBILITY THAT A
VIOLENT CULTURE MAY ALSO HAVE
SOMETHING TO DO WITH WHAT
HAPPENED HERE IN NEWTOWN.
WE ARE GOING TO TAKE A LOOK AT
THE WAY MOVIES AND VIDEO GAMES
COULD BE VERY DESENSITIZING TO
SOME PEOPLE AND WHAT AFFECT THAT
HAS ON THE REST OF US.
[ Male Announcer ]
RED LOBSTER'S CRABFEST
ENDS SOON.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OUR TENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
WHAT STARTS
WITH ADDING A FRIEND...
♪
...COULD END
WITH ADDING A CLOSE FRIEND.
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
>>> PEOPLE KNEW THE GUNMAN IN
THIS MASSACRE SAY HE ENJOYED
PLAYING VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES, IF
PARTICULAR, THEY SAY HE PLAYED
THIS GAME CALLED STARCRAFT.
YOU SEE IT RIGHT THERE.
THE QUESTION, OF COURSE, WHETHER
OR NOT THERE'S A LINK BETWEEN
GAMES LIKE THIS AND REAL-LIFE
VIOLENCE.
WANT TO BRING IN ELIZABETH COHEN
TO TALK ABOUT THIS.
THERE HAVE BEEN NUMEROUS STUDIES
THAT HAVE SHOWED THERE COULD BE
A LING IN TERMS OF BEHAVIOR AND
WATCHING VIOLENT GAMES.
>> THEY ARE CONFLICTING.
SOME STUDIES SAY THERE ISN'T A
LINK, YOU CAN PLAY THESE VIOLENT
VIDEO GAMES, NO INDICATION IT'S
GOING TO MAKE YOU VIOLENT.
THERE ARE OTHER STUDIES THAT
SUGGEST THERE MIGHT BE A LING.
ONE WAS INTERESTING, I'LL GIVE
AS AN EXAMPLE.
THERE'S ONE HAD PEOPLE PLAY
VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES AND SOME
PLAYED NONVIOLENT GAMES.
THE RESEARCHERS STAGED A FIGHT.
SOME GUYS CAME IN AND FOUGHT
LOOKED LIKE IT WAS FOR REAL.
PEOPLE WATCHING THE VIOLENT
VIDEO GAME WERE LESS LIKELY TO
HELP OUT, JUMP IN AND HELP OUT
AND REALIZED THEY DIDN'T
CONSIDER IT TO BE SERIOUS.
>> DESENSITIZED.
>> THEY HAD BEEN WATCHING ALL OF
THE VIOLENCE.
IT'S VERY CONFLICTING.
IT'S REALLY HARD TO SAY
DEFINITIVELY WHAT STUDIES SAY.
>> A MILLION KIDS AND ADULTS
PLAYING GAMES AND THEY NEVER GO
OUT AND KILL ANYBODY, WHAT IS
THE DIFFERENCE?
t ANY IDEA BETWEEN
SOMEBODY WHO WATCHES THESE GAMES
AND ACTS ON THEM?
>> THAT'S THE KEY.
PARENTS ARE SAYING MY CHILD
WATCHES IT ALL THE TIME AND THEY
ARE FINE.
IT MAY BE SOME CHILDREN ARE MORE
VULNERAB
VULNERABLE.
THE PROBLEM IS WE DON'T KNOW.
ALL YOU CAN DO, GIVEN THE MESSY
SITUATION WITH CONFLICTING
SCIENCE IS TO BE AN EMPOWERED
PARENT.
BE A SMART PARENT.
>> SHOULD YOU BE WORRIED?
ESPECIALLY WITH VIOLENT GAMES
SHOULD THERE BE A LIMITATION OR
KIDS TOO YOUNG TO BAN THEM FROM
PLAYING THOSE GAMES EARLY ON?
>> IF YOU -- I THINK SOME
PARENTS WOULD SAY NO VIOLENT
VIDEO GAMES, FORGET IT, YOU'RE
NOT GOING TO DO IT.
SOME PARENTS SAY I LET THEM SEE
VIOLENT MOVIES, WHAT'S WRONG
WITH A VIOLENT VIDEO GAME?
YOU HAVE TO KNOW THE RATING AND
WATCH IT YOURSELF.
GROW
GO ONLINE AND WATCH IT.
LIMIT USE TO COMMON FAMILY
SPACE.
DO NOT PUT A CONSOLE IN THEIR
BEDROOM.
MONITOR YOUR CHILD.
ARE THEY HAVING PROBLEMS,
FIGHTING IN SCHOOL?
PAY ATTENTION TO YOUR KID.
>> PAY ATTENTION TO YOUR KID.
VERY IMPORTANT LESSON, AS WE GO
TO NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, FOR THE
VERY LATEST.
THROHOUT OUR LIVES.
One A Day Men's 50+
IS A COMPLETE MULTIVITAMIN
DESIGNED FOR MEN'S HEALTH
CONCERNS AS WE AGE.
IT HAS 7 ANTIOXIDANTS
TO SUPPORT CELL HEALTH.
One A Day Men's 50+.
but with ADVAIR,
I'm breathing better.
So now I can be in
the scene.
ADVAIR is
clinically proven to help
significantly improve
lung function.
Unlike most COPD medications,
ADVAIR contains both an
anti-inflammatory
and a
long-acting bronchodilator
working together to help improve
your lung function all day.
ADVAIR won't
replace fast-acting inhalers
for sudden symptoms
and should not be used more
than twice a day.
People with
COPD taking ADVAIR
may have a higher chance
of pneumonia.
ADVAIR may increase your
risk of osteoporosis
and some eye problems.
Tell your doctor
if you have a heart condition
or high blood pressure before
taking ADVAIR.
If you're still
having difficulty breathing,
ask your doctor if including
ADVAIR could help
improve your lung function.
Get your
first full
prescription
free
and save
on refills
at
ADVAIRcopd.com.
>>> MOST OF THE STUDENTS IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, ARE BACK
IN SCHOOL TODAY BUT LIFE AS YOU
CAN IMAGINE IS ANYTHING BUT
ROUTINE.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY REMAINS
CLOSED.
FUNERALS HELD FOR TWO MORE
CHILDREN KILLED IN THE MASSACRE.
I'M SUZANNE MALVEAUX IN ATLANTA.
>> HI, SUZANNE.
I'M ASHLEIGH BANFIELD IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THIS IS NEWSROOM SPECIAL
COVERAGE "NEWTOWN REMEMBERS."
TODAY FAMILIES ARE SAYING GOOD
BYE TO A 6-YEAR-OLD GIRL AND A
6-YEAR-OLD BOY.
YESTERDAY, TWO LITTLE BOYS WERE
LAID TO REST.
IT IS A HEARTBREAKING SCENE THAT
IS PLAYING OUT OVER AND OVER AND
IT WILL CONTINUE TO DO SO THIS
WEEK.
CONNECTICUT'S GOVERNOR IS TRYING
TO COMFORT THE GRIEVING FAMILIES
HERE.
>> THE REALITY WITH RESPECT TO
THE RELATIVES, AS YOU TRY TO
FEEL THEIR PAIN, BUT YOU CAN'T.
YOU TRY TO FIND SOME WORDS THAT
YOU HOPE WILL BE ADEQUATE,
KNOWING THAT THEY'LL BE
INADEQUATE.
AND YOU SEE LITTLE COFFINS AND
YOUR HEART HAS TO ACHE.
>> GOVERNOR DAN MALLOY.
WE ALSO WANT TO UPDATE YOU ON
THE NEW DEVELOPMENTS IN THE
AFTERMATH OF THE TRAGEDY IN
NEWTOWN.
SCHOOLS ARE BACK IN SESSION FOR
THE FIRST TIME SINCE FRIDAY'S
MASSACRE.
á SITE GHT
A BRIGHT SPOT.
MORE POLICE AND EXTRA COUNSELORS
ARE ON HAND TO MAKE SURE THE
TRANSITION GOES SMOOTHLY.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY, WHERE
THIS MASSACRE TOOK PLACE, THAT
WILL REMAIN CLOSED FOR THE
FORESEEABLE FUTURE UNTIL FURTHER
NOTICE.
MORE FUNERAL SERVICES HELDú,U)
TODAY.
ONE OF THEM, 6-YEAR-OLD JESSICA
REKOS.
SHE LOVED HORSES AND SHE WAS
EXPECTING A BRAND-NEW PAIR OF
COWGIRL BOOTS FOR CHRISTMAS, HER
PARENTS TELL CNN.
ALSO, A FORMER DIRECTOR OF
SECURITY FOR NEWTOWN SCHOOLS
SHEDDING LIGHT ON THE GUNMAN WHO
PERPETRATED THIS HORROR.
THAT PERSON WAS ASSIGNED TO KEEP
TRACK OF STUDENTS WHO WERE
HAVING PROBLEMS, STUDENTS
INCLUDING ADAM LANZA.
BUT HE ALSO SAYSÑ"á HE NEVER
THOUGHT OF ADAM LANZA
PARTICULARLY AS A THREAT.
WE WANT TO UPDATE YOU MORE ON
THE INVESTIGATION INTO THIS
MASSIVE CRIME.
MORE INFORMATION, NEW
INFORMATION THAT WE'RE JUST
GETTING IN NOW FROM THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER.
OUR DEB FEYERICK HAS BEEN
WORKING THAT PART OF THE STORY.
SHE'S OUTSIDE OF THE LANZA HOME
WITH MORE DETAILS ON THAT AINNG.
>> Reporter: A NUMBER OF
INVESTIGATORS ARE ON SCENE RIGHT
NOW LOOKING AT WHATEVER THEY CAN
THAT REMAINS INSIDE THE HOUSE.
ONE OF THE BIG PROBLEMS ABOUT
THE INVESTIGATION, ASHLEIGH,
AUTHORITIES ARE CONFIRMING IN
FACT THE COMPUTER THAT BELONGED
TO ADAM LANZA WAS IN FACT
SMASHED.
SO THEY ARE HAVING DIFFICULTY
RE-CREATING ALL OF THE FORENSIC
INFORMATION.
WE WANT TO TALK TO YOU ABOUT A
CONVERSATION WITH THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER, H. WAYNE CARVER.
HE CONFIRMS TO CNN TOXICOLOGY
TESTS WERE PERFORMED ON THE BODY
OF ADAM LANZA TO DETERMINE
WHETHER IN FACT HE WAS ON ANY
KINDS OF MEDICATION THAT MAY
HAVE TRIGGERED THE VIOLENT
OUTBURST.
THOUGH THE MEDICAL EXAMINER WAS
TOLD THAT IN FACT HE HAS
ASPERGERS, THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER'S BEING EXTRA CAREFUL,
TRYING TO DETERMINE THAT'S ALL
GOING ON THIS YOUNG MAN AND
TRYING TO SEE IF THERE WAS
SOMETHING DEEPER, SOMETHING
PATHOLOGICAL, PSYCHIATRIC.
THE BODIES OF THE MOM AND SON,
AUTOPSIES WERE COMPLETED.
THEY'VE NOT BEEN RELEASED.
NOBODY'S CLAIMED THEM.
WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN, THE
BODIES WILL BE RELEASED AND THEN
BURIED BEFORE ANY NOTIFICATION
IS GIVEN, TO ANY MEMBERS OF THE
PRESS.
FAMILY WANTS TO KEEP IT PRIVATE,
MAKE SURE NOTHING HAPPENS DURING
THE BURIAL PROCESS.
YOU KNOW IT TOOK PLACE HERE.
ADAM LANZA ALLEGEDLY SHOOTING
HIS MOTHER WHILE SHE SLEPT IN
HER PAJAMAS IN HER BED.
HE SHOT HER FOUR TIMES IN THE
HEAD.
THE COMPUTER, THE SMASHED
COMPUTER, NOT CLEAR WHAT POINT
THAT WAS ACTUALLY DONE.
BUT AFTER HE KILLED HIS MOM, HE
WENT OVER TO THE SCHOOL.
HE KILLED HIMSELF AFTER HIS
RAMPAGE WITH A SINGLE SHOT, THAT
ALSO TO THE HEAD.
ACCORDING TO THE DIVORCE
DOCUMENTS THE MOTHER WAS IN
CHARGE OF HIS MENTAL CARE.
WHAT'S CRAZY, ASHLEIGH, THERE
WAS A THREE-YEAR PERIOD IN WHICH
ADAM LANZA SEEMS TO HAVE
DISAPPEARED.
HE WAS -- LOOKED LIKE HE WAS
PURSUING AN EDUCATION BUT EVEN
THEN THINGS WERE GOING ON.
LITTLE IS KNOWN ABOUT ADAM
LANZA.
BUT AS A GAWKY HIGH SCHOOL
FRESHMAN IN 2007, LANZA SEEMED
SO VULNERABLE THE FORMER SCHOOL
SECURITY DIRECTOR AT NEWTOWN
HIGH SCHOOL TELLS CNN HE WARNED
HIS SCHOOL OFFICERS TO KEEP AN
EYE ON THE CHILD SO HE WOULD NOT
BE PICKED ON OR BULLIED.
LANZA WAS ALSO ASSIGNED TO A
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST, SAYS THE
SECURITY DIRECTOR.
THE LANZA JOINED THE TECH CLUB
HE REMAINED WITHDRAWN.
IN 2008, AGE 16, LANZA ENROLLED
ANDERSON COOPER A STUDENT AT
WESTERN CONNECTICUT STATE
UNIVERSITY, 15 MINUTES FROM HIS
HOME, TAKING AMONG OTHER CLASSES
GERMAN, COMPUTER SCIENCE,
AMERICAN HISTORY, AND MACRO
ECONOMICS.
HE DROPPED OUT IN 2009, AND DID
NOT RETURN.
LANZA'S HIGH SCHOOL FRIEND RAN
INTO NANCY LANZA A FEW YEARS
AGO, HE SAYS THE MOM DESCRIBED
ADAM AS DOING WELL IN COLLEGE
AND TOLD HIM HE HAD TAKEN HIM
SHOOTING AS A HOBBY AND LIKED TO
GO TO THE GUN RANGE.
WHAT WAS INTERESTING, NANCY
LANZA WAS DOING EVERYTHING SHE
COULD TO MAINSTREAM HER SON.
HE CLEARLY HAD ISSUES BUT SHE
WAS TRYING TO KEEP THINGS AS
NORMAL AS POSSIBLE AND GETTING
HIM TO DIFFERENT SCHOOLS WHERE
SHE COULD TAP INTO WHAT'S
DESCRIBED AS HIS GENIUS, HIS
SORT OF SUPERB INTELLECT.
WE DID PEEK TO A FRIEND WHO KNEW
NANCY AND HE SAYS SHE KEPT A GUN
LOCK BOX IN THE BASEMENT OF THE
HOME.
HE SAW IT EIGHT MONTHS AGO WHEN
HE WAS IN THE HOME DOING WORK.
AND HE ALSO SAID THAT ONE OF THE
REASONS THAT SHE ULTIMATELY
TAUGHT HER SON HOW TO SHOOT OR
TOOK HIM TO THE GUN RANGES,
BECAUSE SHE DIDN'T LIKE TO LEAVE
HIM ALONE FOR BIG PERIODS OF
TIME.
SHE'S KRDESCRIBED AS A COUNTRY
GIRL, LIKED SHOOTING AND GOING
TO THE AERANG AND TOOK ADAM WIT
HER AND THAT'S WHEN HE DEVELOPED
A LIKE FOR THE SPORT.
ASHLEIGH?
>> DEB, IT'S JUST SO TROUBLING
TO HEAR DETAILS, THE GUN LOCK
BOX AND THIS MOTHER, WHO WAS
HOME SCHOOLING AND WORKING SO
HARD OR TRYING TO DO THE
NORMALCY SCHOOLING, FOR REGULAR
STUDENTS.
VERY, VERY UPSETTING, INDEED.
DEB FEYERICK REPORTING FOR US
LIVE.
>>> WE KNOW THE SCHOOL'S A CRIME
SCENE.
STUDENTS AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY ARE NOT RETURNING TO
CLASS TODAY.
WHEN THEY GO BACK, IT WILL BE A
NEW SCHOOL.
THE TOWN'S UPDATING A FORMER
MIDDLE SCHOOL IN NEARBY MONROE.
THAT IS WHERE MY COLLEAGUE
ASHLEIGH TOOK A LOOK.
>> Reporter: WHILE THE KIDS IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT ARE GOING
TO BE RETURNING TO SCHOOL TODAY,
THE KIDS FROM SANDY HOOK WILL
NOT BE.
THAT'S BECAUSE THEY'RE GOING TO
COME HERE TO THE MONROE MIDDLE
SCHOOL CAMPUS.
LOOK TO THE LEFT.
THE CHALK HILL SCHOOL, A SCHOOL
BECAUSE OF DECLINING ENROLLMENT
CLOSED DOWN AND SET TO REOPEN AS
A COMMUNITY CENTER BUT NOW
MONROE COUNTY HAS DECIDED TO
AVAIL ITS SERVICES TO KIDS OF
SANDY HOOK.
LOOK ACROSS THE STREET AT THE
SIGN THAT HAS SHOWN UP "WELCOME
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY" HEART
WARMING TO SEE THAT.
HERE'S HOW IT'S GOING TO WORK.
THEY'RE NOT GOING TO BE HERE
TODAY.
WE DON'T KNOW EXACTLY WHEN
THEY'LL BE HERE.
LOOK UP THERE, THERE'S A POLICE
OFFICER WHO IS BLOCKING THE
ENTRANCE TO THE MEDIA.
WE WANT TO BE RESPECTFUL.
THEY'RE ALLOWING TEACHERS THAT
ARE GOING INTO AN ADJACENT
MIDDLE SCHOOL AND PEOPLE WHO ARE
MOVING ALL OF THE CONTENTS FROM
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY ACTUALLY
INTO CHALK HILL SO WHEN THE
CHILDREN ARRIVE HERE, THE
ARTWORK FROM THEIR ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL WILL BE ON THE WALLS
THERE.
THEIR DESKS WILL BE IN PLACE
AND THERE'S EVEN REPORTEDLY
PHOTOGRAPHS THAT WEREA TAKEN AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY OF WHAT
THE CLASSROOMS LOOK LIKE SO
PROFESSIONAL MOVERS COULD MOVE
EVERYTHING IN AND MAKE IT LOOK
EXACTLY THE SAME WAS REALLY A
REMARKABLE FEAT GIVEN ALL OF THE
DURESS, EVERYONE'S UNDER.
OVER THE LAST COUPLE OF DAYS,
TRUCKS ARE BEEN COMING UP AND
DOWN DELIVERING EQUIPMENT, DESKS
AND THE GEAR THAT YOU NEED TO
ACTUALLY FUNCTIONALLY MAKE A
SCHOOL HAPPEN FOR LITTLE
CHILDREN.
>> IT IS A SOMBER REALITY FOR
NEWTOWN, THE FUNERALS ARE GOING
ON FOR DAY.
YESTERDAY WE SAW TWO FIRST GRADE
BOYS BEING BURIED.
TODAY A 6-YEAR-OLD GIRL.
SANDRA IS JOINING US FROM
NEWTOWN WHERE YOU HAVE BEEN
SEEING FOLKS TRYING TO COPE WITH
WAVES OF GRIEF.
I IMAGINE THIS WILL CONTINUE FOR
SOME TIME.
TODAY THERE'S A LITTLE GIRL,
JESSICA REKOS BEING BURIED.
WE KNOW A LITTLE BIT ABOUT HER.
>> Reporter: ABSOLUTELY.
IT'S JUST HEARTBREAKING TO SEE
WHAT THIS COMMUNITY IS DEALING
WITH AND WE SAW THE FUNERAL
PROCESSION PASS THROUGH THE
STREETS HERE.
PEOPLE ARE CONTANTLY COMING BY
THE MAKESHIFT MEMORIAL IN THE
MIDDLE OF TOWN AND TRYING TO PAY
CONDOLENCES TO LIVES LOST.
YOU MENTIONED BEING LAID TO REST
TODAY.
JESSICA REKOS, 6 YEARS OLD.
ACCORDING TO HER FAMILY, SHE
LOVED HORSES.
SHE COULDN'T WAIT UNTIL HER
10-YEAR-OLD BIRTHDAY WHEN SHE
WAS PROMISED TO GET A HORSE.
SHE LIKED TO DRESS IN COWBOY
SHE'S BEING REMEMBERED AS THE
FAMILY'S CEO.
SHE WOULD PLAN EVERYTHING AND
WRITE DOWN JOURNALS AND NOTES
AND LEAVE THEM FOR THE FAMILY.
HERE'S WHAT THEY SAY THEY
REMEMBER MOST ABOUT HER.
>> SHE WAS A BALL OF FIRE.
SHE RULED THE ROOST.
SHE --
>> LITTLE CEO WE CALLED HER.
SHE WAS -- SHE WAS THE BOSS.
>> SHE IS SURVIVED BY HER TWO
BROTHERS.
ALSO BEING LAID TO REST TODAY IS
JAMES MA TOLLY, 6 YEARS OLD AND
FAMILY MEMBERS SAY THAT HE LOVED
TO WEAR T-SHIRTS AND SHORTS,
REGARDLESS OF THE WEATHER, AND
HE LOVED TO SWIM.
HE SWAM LIKE A FISH.
LOVED SPORTS.
HE SANG AT THE TOP OF HIS LUNGS.
THESE ARE SO MANY DIFFERENT
STORIES WE'RE HEARING ABOUT
REMARKABLE CHILDREN WHO,
UNFORTUNATELY, THEIR LIVES WERE
TAKEN WAY TOO SOON.
>> I DON'T KNOW WHY, BUT MAKES
ME FEEL BETTER WHEN I LEARN MORE
ABOUT THESE KIDS AND WHAT THEY
WERE LOOK LIKE.
THERE ARE TWO, VISITATION FOR
TWO OTHER STUDENTS, CHARLOTTE
BACON AND DANIEL BARTON.
ARE WE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THEM
AS WELL?
>> Reporter: YEAH.
THIS IS UNFORTUNATELY GOING TO
BE THE NEW NORMAL FOR THE NEXT
FEW DAY, SUZANNE, JUST FUNERAL
AFTER FUNERAL IN THE DAYS TO
COME.
YOU MENTIONED CHARLOTTE BACON,
6.
OUTGOING REDHEAD.
HER SMILE LIT UP A ROOM.
SURVIVED BY AN OLDER BROTHER WHO
ATTENDED SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
SHE LOVED THE COLOR PINK.
SHE WORE HER FAVORITE PINK DRESS
TO SCHOOL, ACCORDING TO HER
FAMILY THOUGH SHE WAS SUPPOSED
TO WAIT FOR THE HOLIDAYS TO WEAR
IT.
LEARNING ABOUT DANIEL, PASSED
AWAY, 7 YEARS OLD.
HE WAS AN OLD SOUL.
OPEN DOORS FOR STRANGERS AND
OLDER PEOPLE AND STAND THERE AND
HIS FAMILY WOULD LEAVE AND HE'S
STILL OPENING THE DOOR FOR
PEOPLE.
CLEARLY A WONDERFUL SOUL AND HAD
SO MUCH LOVE FOR OTHERS AND
AGAIN, SUZANNE, AS YOU
MENTIONED, IT'S SO HEARTBREAKING
TO HEAR STORIES, AS YOU LEARN
MORE ABOUT THESE INDIVIDUAL
CHILDREN, MORE ABOUT THEIR
PERSONALTIES AND WHAT TYPE OF
LITTLE CHILDREN AND PEOPLE THEY
WERE.
>> REALLY BEAUTIFUL.
MUST BE HARD TO TRY TO FIGURE
OUT A EULOGY FOR A 6-YEAR-OLD,
WHAT YOU ACTUALLY SAY BUT THEY
BREAK IT DOWN.
IT'S VERY SIMPLE.
REMAINS YOU, THEY ARE JUST 6
YEARS OLD.
THANK YOU.
MANY PEOPLE ARE WONDERING, HOW
DO YOU HELP ALL OF THESE PEOPLE
IMPACTED BY THIS?
WE PUT A LIST TOGETHER.
CHARITABLE ORGANIZATIONS ON
CNN.COM/IMPACT.
THERE IS A LOT TO BE DONE.
>>> POLICE SAY ADAM LANZA USED A
GUN LIKE THIS ONE TO KILL HIS
VICTIMS AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
WE'LL TAKE A LOOK AT THE AR-15
223 CALIBER RIFLE AND WHY SALES
ARE SKYROCKETING.
I GAVE BIRTH TO MY DAUGHTER
ON MAY 18TH,
FIVE DAYS LATER,
I HAD A MASSIVE HEART ATTACK.
BAYER ASPIRIN WAS THE FIRST
THING THE EMTS GAVE ME.
NOW, I'M ON
A BAYER ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Male Announcer ] BE SURE
TO TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE YOU BEGIN
AN ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Woman ]
LEARN FROM MY STORY.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE RHYTHM OF LIFE.
[ whistle blowing ]
WHERE DO YOU HEAR THAT BEAT?
CAMPBELL'S HEALTHY REQUEST SOUP
LETS YOU HEAR IT...
IN YOUR HEART.
[ basketball bouncing ]
HEART HEALTHY.
GREAT TASTE.
MMM...
[ Male Announcer ] SOUNDS GOOD.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
SINGLE DAY IN THIS COUNTRY.
JUST THIS MORNING, ANOTHER
MULTIPLE SHOOTING.
IF YOU CAN BELIEVE THIS.
THIS IS IN COLORADO, POLICE SAY
FOUR PEOPLE FOUND DEAD IN A HOME
IN LONGMONT, 15 MILES FROM
BOULDER.
POLICE ARE TREATING THIS CASE AS
A MURDER/SUICIDE.
HIGH PROFILE SHOOTINGS FOLLOWED
BY THREATS OF ON COPYCAT KILLERS
AUTHORITIESES ARE TAKING NO
CHANCES.
POLICE ARRESTED THREE TEENAGERS
IN SEPARATE INDENT WHOSE
THREATENED TO KILL OUT SIMILAR
ATTACKS OF THE MASSACRE.
ARRESTED IN HIS UNTIL SOUTH
CAROLINA FOR ALLEGEDLY HAVING
WEAPONS IN HIS CAR, INCLUDING A
LOADED .22 CALIBER HANDGUN.
18-YEAR-OLD SERGIO, ALLEGEDLY
LEFT MESSAGES ONLINE SAYING HE
SUPPORTS THE ACTIONS OF THE
SCHOOL SHOOTER.
AND THEN A TEENAGER IN TENNESSEE
ARRESTED FOR POSTING MESSAGES ON
FACEBOOK SAYING HE FELT LIKE
GOING ON A RAMPAGE.
NOW EXPERTS SAY IT'S GOING TO BE
DIFFICULT TO PROSECUTE THE CASES
BECAUSE OF FREEDOM OF SPEECH.
>>> SUZANNE, ONE OF THE LARGEST
SPORTING GOODS RETAILERS ARE IN
THE WORLD DECIDED TO SUSPEND THE
SALE OF SOME OF THE
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLES ACROSS THE
COUNTRY CALLED DICK'S SPORTING
GOODS, REMOVED ALL OF THE GUNS
FROM THE STORE IT HAS CLOSEST TO
THE COMMUNITY WHERE I AM,
NEWTOWN.
THIS IS OF COURSE WHERE THE
SHOOT OWING CURED ON FRIDAY.
THE COMPANY SAYS IT MADE THIS
MOVE OUT OF RESPECT FOR THE
VICTIMS AND OF COURSE FOR THEIR
FAMILIES, AS WELL.
AND ALSO, IN LIGHT OF THAT
STORY, SOME GUN SHOPS ARE
REPORTING A SPIKE, A SPIKE, IN
THE SALES OF SEMIAUTOMATIC
WEAPONS INCLUDING THE TYPE OF
GUN THAT WAS USED TO KILL THOSE
20 CHILDREN AND 6 FACULTY
MEMBERS AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
OUR CHRIS LAWRENCE FOUND OUT THE
AR-15 MODEL IS THE MOST POPULAR
RIFLE IN AMERICA.
>> Reporter: THE AR-15 HAS
ALWAYS BEEN A TOP SELLER AT THIS
VIRGINIA GUN SHOP.
BUT CHUCK SAYS SINCE FRIDAY'S
SHOOTING, SALES HAVE BEEN
SURGING.
>> PEOPLE WANT TO GET THEM
BEFORE THE GOVERNMENT IMPOSES
ANY RESTRICTIONS AND THEY'RE
BUYING THEM UP IN RECORD NUMBERS
RIGHT NOW.
>> Reporter: WE WEREN'T IN THE
STORE FOR FIVE MINUTES BEFORE
CUSTOMERS STARTED CALLING FOR
GUNS AND AMMO.
>> THOSE MAGAZINES ARE SELLING
FAST.
IN ANTICIPATION OF POSSIBLE BAN
ON MAGAZINES.
>> Reporter: AND HE CAN'T KEEP
ENOUGH OF THE AR-15.
>> BUT WE DO HAVE IN STOCK IN
THE STORE THREE OTHER GUNS THAT
ARE OF THE SAME QUALITY AS THE
BUSHMASTER.
>> Reporter: HOW MANY ROUNDS CAN
THIS FIRE PER SECOND?
>> HOW FAST CAN YOU PULL THE
TRIGGER?
>> Reporter: THE AR-15 IS
SEMIAUTOMATIC, ONE BULLET PER
TRIGGER PULL.
AVERAGE CLIP CARRIES 30 ROUNDS.
IT'S A VARIATION OF THE
MILITARY'S M-16.
IT LOOKS TOUGH, OMINOUS.
POLICE SAY ADAM LANZA USED AN
AR-15 IN CONNECTICUT.
IT WAS ALSO USED TO KILL 12
PEOPLE IN A COLORADO MOVIE
THEATER THIS SUMMER.
WHO BUYS THIS WEAPON?
>> EVERYBODY.
>> Reporter: GUNS AND AMMO
MAGAZINE ESTIMATES THAT 1.5
MILLION HAVE BEEN MADE IN THE
LAST FIVE YEARS ALONE.
DEALERS SAY, IT'S MOST POPULAR
RIFLE IN AMERICA.
FOR GOOD REASON.
HOW QUICKLY COULD SOMEONE USE
THIS RIFLE?
>> TO SHOOT IT?
VERY LITTLE TRAINING TO SHOOT
IT.
>> Reporter: IT WEIGHS ABOUT
EIGHT POUNDS, TAKES ALL KINDS OF
AMMO.
AND IT CAN BE EASILY CUSTOMIZED
WITH VARIOUS LASERS, STOCKS AND
GUN LOCKS.
THE AR-15 IS ACCURATE AND IT IS
VERY LITTLE KICK.
>> THERE'S LITERALLY NO RECOIL
FROM THIS BECAUSE YOU ARE
SHOOTING A HIGH-POWERED .22
ROUND.
THAT'S ONE OF THE THINGS THAT
MAKE IT VERY CONTROLLABLE.
YOU CAN BUY THESE AT 1700
WALMART STORES.
THERE ARE MAGAZINES DEDICATED TO
THE AR-15.
THERE ARE LITERALLY MILLIONS OF
THESE RIFLES IN HOMES ACROSS
AMERICA.
HONESTLY, THAT SHOWS NO SIGNS OF
SLOWING DOWN.
CHRIS LAWRENCE, CNN, WASHINGTON.
>>> GOING TO TAKE A LOOK AT
FEDERAL AND STATE GUN LAWS AS WE
CONTINUE OUR SPECIAL COVERAGE OF
THE CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTING.
>> IT'S NOT SO MUCH AS RETHINK
IT BUT YOU KNOW WHO WOULD HAVE
EVER THOUGHT IN AMERICA OR
ANYWHERE IN THE WORLD THAT
CHILDREN WOULD BE SLAUGHTERED?
YOU KNOW THAT -- IT'S CHANGED
ME.
BUT WITH THAT BEING SAID, PEOPLE
ARE AFRAID TO TALK ABOUT SOME
THINGS THAT JUST BASICALLY
SHOULD BE TALKED.
I DON'T KNOW OF ANYBODY THAT
GOES HUNTING WITH AN ASSAULT
RIFLE.ES TO
FINANCIAL OBSTACLES
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAND.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
>>> THE SCHOOL MASSACRE NEAR
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, HAS MORE
PRO-GUN LAWMAKERS CHANGING THEIR
VIEWS.
SENATOR ELECT JOE DONNELLY OF
INDIANA IS THE LATEST DEMOCRAT
ENDORSES BY THE NATIONAL RIFLE
ASSOCIATION, WHO NOW SAYS THAT
HE IS COMMITTED TO LOOKING AT
NEW WAYS TO TIGHTEN GUN LAWS.
HE TOLD CNN, QUOTE, I THINK WE
HAVE A RESPONSIBILITY TO MAKE
SURE THAT THIS NEVER HAPPENS
AGAIN.
AND ALSO, WEST VIRGINIA SENATOR
JOE MANCHIN ALSO A DEMOCRAT,
ALSO A LONGTIME MEMBER OF THE
NRA, SAID THAT HE HAS CHANGED
HIS POSITION AFTER THE MASSACRE
AND NOW SUPPORTS GUN CONTROL
LEGISLATION.
LAWMAKERS ARE HEARING TODAY FROM
MORE THAN 20 FAMILY MEMBERS AND
VICTIMS OF MASS SHOOTINGS ACROSS
THIS COUNTRY.
THOSE PEOPLE ALL CAME TOGETHER
ON CAPITOL HILL AND DECIDED THEY
NEEDED TO MEET WITH LEADERS IN
CONGRESS AND LEADERS IN THE
WHITE HOUSE.
THEY ARE DEMANDING THAT THEY
SERIOUSLY ADDRESS GUN VIOLENCE
IN AMERICA.
EACH PERSON WHO CAME HAD A VERY
EMOTIONAL STORY TO SHARE AND
THEY INCLUDED A FATHER WHOSE
24-YEAR-OLD SON WAS KILLED IN
AREPO
AURORA, COLORADO, WHO SHIELDED
HIS GIRLFRIEND WHO THE SHOOTER
TOOK SO MANY.
A MOTHER GUNNED DOWN ON A
CHICAGO BUS.
A FATHER LOST HIS 15-YEAR-OLD
SON DURING COLUMBINE TRAGEDY.
AND THE LIST WENT ON AND ON.
AND THE PHOTOS KEPT COMING OUT.
THEIR MESSAGE, ABOUT 32 PEOPLE
ARE KILLED EVERY SINGLE DAY BY
GUNS IN THIS COUNTRY AND THAT IT
HAS GOT TO STOP.
>> TODAY, THERE WILL BE 32 MORE
FAMILIES THAT KNOW THE PAIN AND
OR THAT YOU JUST HEARD HERE
TODAY.
SO WE PAY A LOT OF ATTENTION AND
APPROPRIATELY SO TO THESE MASS
SHOOTINGS, THE ONE THAT ANDRE'S
SON MIRACULOUSLY SURVIVED.
BUT WE ALSO HAVE TO BE AWARE
THIS HAPPENS IN OUR NATION EVERY
DAY AND AS YOU'RE GOING TO HEAR
TODAY, AS A NATION, WE ARE
BETTER THAN THIS.
>> THAT WAS DAN GROSS, SPEARHEAD
TODAY'S CALL FOR ACTION.
HE'S THE HEAD OF THE BRADY
CAMPAIGN WHICH IS A NONPROFIT
THAT HAS LONG FOUGHT TO REFORM
THE GUN INDUSTRY THROUGH LAWS
AND ALSO THROUGH EDUCATION,
SUZANNE.
>> CURRENT GUN LAWS ARE AS
VARIED AS STATES THAT GOVERN
THEM.
GEORGE HOWELL IS TAKING A LOOK
AT VARIED REGULATIONS.
JUST WATCH.
>> WHAT HAPPENED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, HAS PUT THE
SPOTLIGHT ON GUN LAWS IN THE
U.S.
GOVERNMENT DANNEL MALLOY SAYS
WITH HIS STATE'S TOUGH GUN
REGULATIONS IT'S NOT ENOUGH.
>> IN THE ABSENCE OF A FEDERAL
FRAMEWORK IN WHICH WE LIMIT THE
EXPLOSIVE NATURE OF THE WEAPONS
AND AMMUNITION THAT'S USED, NO
STATE WOULD EVER BE SAFE BASED
ON SIMPLY ITS OWN LAWS.
THAT'S WHY THE BRADY BILL,
THAT'S WHY THE ASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN, WAS SO VERY IMPORTANT.
>> Reporter: THE ONLY FEDERAL
BAN ON ASSAULT RIFLES BECAME LAW
IN 1994 BUT EXPIRED IN 2004.
CONNECTICUT STILL HAS A SIMILAR
LAW ON ITS BOOKS BANNING ASSAULT
RIFLES BUT THAT LAW DIDN'T APPLY
TO THE BUSHMASTER AR-15 RIFLE
ADAM LANZA USED DURING HIS
SHOOTING RAMPAGE.
THE STATE'S GUN LAW WOULD HAVE
BEEN BANED THE 30 ROUND MAGAZINE
LANZA USED.
>> AS EVERYONES AWARE FROM THE
TRAJ DOIF LA
TRAGEDY 0 LAST FRIDAY, MAGAZINE
IS LEGAL AND YOU DON'T NEED A
BACKGROUND STATE TO GET THOSE
TYPES OF MILITARY-STYLE WEAPONS.
>> Reporter: ROBIN THOMAS SAYS
FEDERAL LAWS ARE MINIMAL, AT
BEST.
ACCORDING TO THE BUREAU OF
ALCOHOL, TOBACCO AND FIREARMS
THE U.S. GOVERNMENT REQUIRES A
PERSON MUST BE 21 TO PURCHASE A
HANDGUN FROM A LICENSED DEALER,
18 YEARS OLD TO PURCHASE A LONG
GUN, LIKE A RIFLE, FROM A
LICENSED DEALER, BUT FEDERAL LAW
DOES NOT REGULATE PRIVATE SALES
BETWEEN INDIVIDUALS OR SALES AT
GUN SHOWS OR ONLINE.
IT'S A STATE'S RIGHT ISSUE.
THE BADI CAMPAIGN FOR GUN
CONTROL RATES FIVE STATES ATOP
OF THE SCORECARD FOR GUN
REGULATIONS WITH CALIFORNIA AT
TOP OF THE LIST.
>> WE HAVE UNIVERSAL BACKGROUND
CHECKS SO YOU NEED A BACKGROUND
CHECK ON ANY TRANSFER OF SALE OF
A FIREARM, WHETHER IT'S A GUN
DEALER, GUN SHOW, PRIVATE
SELLER.
>> Reporter: LAWS THAT CAN BE
AVOIDED IN SOME CASES SIMPLY BY
CROSSING STATE LINES.
THE BRADY CAMPAIGN'S SCORECARD
RATES THESE STATES AS HAVING THE
WEAKEST GUN REGULATIONS.
>> CALIFORNIA, WE MIGHT HAVE
GOOD, STRONG GUN LAWS BUT IF YOU
WANT TO BUY AN ASSAULT WEAPON
YOU DRIVE ACROSS TO NEVADA OR
ARIZONA AND YOU CAN BUY THEM
THERE EASILY WITHOUT A
BACKGROUND CHECK AND BRING THEM
ACROSS THE BORDER.
WE DO NEED BASIC MEASURES AT THE
FEDERAL LEVEL.
>> GEORGE, THAT'S A PATCHWORK OF
DIFFERENT LAWS FROM DIFFERENT
STATES.
IT'S UNBELIEVABLE WHEN YOU THINK
ABOUT IT, FROM ONE STATE TO THE
NEXT.
ALL YOU DO IS CROSS THE BOARD
SOMEWHERE BUY A WEAPON IN
ANOTHER STATE.
CALIFORNIA ONE OF THE TOUGHEST,
HOW S/xP
>> YOU HEARD THERE ARE
BACKGROUND CHECKS BUT THEY
REGULATE THE GUN OWNERS.
THEY BAN ASSAULT RIFLES.
THERE'S A WAITING PERIOD IN
CALIFORNIA, TEN-DAY WAITING
PEER.
LOOK AT NEW YORK, 90-DAY WAITING
PERIOD THERE.
WHEN YOU PUT MEASURES IN PLACE,
ADVOCATES FOR GUN LAWS I SHOULD
SAY THEY SAY THAT THAT MAKES A
BIG DIFFERENCE.
>> WHY IS IT THAT THESE LAWS DO
NOT APPLY FOR PRIVATE SELLERS OF
THE GUN SHOWS?
WHY IS IT ALLOWED?
>> STATE BY STATE.
WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT GUN SHOWS,
THAT'S THE BIG LOOPHOLE.
UNLIKE A LICENSED DEAL, GUN
SHOWS DON'T HAVE TO DO
BACKGROUND CHECKS AND THEY MAY
MISS SELF-THINGS.
PEOPLE ARE PROHIBITED BY FEDERAL
LAW FROM OWNING GUNS IF THEY HIT
A LONG LIST OF SELF-THINGS.
IF YOU'RE A CONVICTED FELOFELON
DISHONORABLY DISCHARGED FROM THE
ARMED SERVICES.
A LONG LIST OF THINGS THERE.
WHEN YOU DON'T HAVE TO DO THE
BACKGROUND CHECK YOU MAY NOT
KNOW AND THEN YOU CAN MAKE THE
SALE.
>> DO YOU THINK THERE'S A WILL
HERE?
IS THERE A POLITICAL WILL TO
PUSH THIS FORWARD?
SEEMS LIKE PEOPLE ARE TALKING
ABOUT CHANGING THIS OR SOMETHING
IN PLACE.
>> YOU KNOW, JUST DIGGING INTO
THE LAW, AND THEN HEARING FROM
PEOPLE ON BOTH SIDES, YOU CAN
TELL THAT PEOPLE WHO SUPPORT GUN
LAWS, THEY WANT TO SEE SOMETHING
CHANGE.
YOU CAN ALSO TELL PEOPLE WHO OWN
GUNS AND STAND FOR THE SECOND
AMENDMENT, THEY WANT TO SEE SOME
SORT OF CHANGE AS WELL.
YOU SEE IT ON SOCIAL MEDIA.
YOU SEE PEOPLE TALKING ABOUT IT.
YOU GET THE SENSE THAT SOMETHING
WILL CHANGE, GIVEN WHAT WE SAW
IN NEWTOWN.
>> THANK YOU, APPRECIATE IT.
>>> FOUR DAYS SINCE THAT GUNMAN
OPENED FIRE ON THAT FIRST DAY
THAT FIRST GRADE CLASS AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY.
WE'RE STILL LEARNING ABOUT THE
MANY VICTIMS, AS WELL AS HEROES.
HEAR FROM ONE MAN WHO HELPED
KIDS ESCAPE THE MASSACRE.
>> THE TWO BOYS MOSTLY TALKED
AND THEY SAID, WE CAN'T GO BACK
TO THAT SCHOOL -- WE CAN'T --
>> WE CAN'T GO BACK.
>> OUR TEACHER -- OUR TEACHER'S
DEAD.
[ Female Announcer ]
WHAT IF THE NEXT BIG THING,
ISN'T A THING AT ALL?
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
♪
BECOMING
PART OF THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
TREES WILL TALK TO NETWORKS
WILL TALK TO SCIENTISTS
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE.
CARS WILL TALK TO ROAD SENSORS
WILL TALK TO STOPLIGHTS
ABOUT TRAFFIC EFFICIENCY.
THE AMBULANCE WILL TALK
TO PATIENT RECORDS
WILL TALK TO DOCTORS
ABOUT SAVING LIVES.
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
THE NEXT BIG THING?
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
♪
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
♪
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
>>> GETTING NEW INFORMATION FROM
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER IN THE
AFTERMATH OF THE TRAGEDY IN
NEWTOWN.
HE TELLS OUR SISTER NETWORK HLN
AUTOPSIES ON THE BODIES OF ADAM
LANZA AND HIS MOTHER NANCY LANZA
ARE COMPLETE.
NO ONE HAS CLAIMED THE BODIES
YET.
HE TELLS THAT IS NANCY LANZA WAS
SHOT FOUR TIMES IN THE HEAD
WHILE SLEEPING.
ADAM LANZA DIED OF A SINGLE
GUNSHOT WOUND TO THE HEAD.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER SAYING HE
WAS TOLD THAT ADAM LANZA HAD
BEEN DIAGNOSED WITH ASPERGER'S
SYNDROME BUT THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER EM PHASIZES HE DOES NO
KNOW IF THE DIAGNOSE IS CORRECT
AND THERE'S NO LINK BETWEEN THE
DIAGNOSIS AND VIOLENT BEHAVIOR.
>> VERY DISTRESSING INFORMATION,
SUZANNE.
WE'RE ALSO GETTING DETAILS OF
SOME OF THE THINGS THAT HAPPENED
ON THE DAY OF THE MASSACRE.
AND ONE OF THE MORE HARROWING
STORIES IS WHAT HAPPENED WITH
THE GROUP OF SIX CHILDREN WHO
WERE IN ONE OF THE CLASSROOMS
WHERE THEIR TEACHER WAS SHOT
DEAD BEFORE THEIR EYES.
THEY ESCAPED AND RAN FOR THEIR
LIVES.
SUZANNE, THEY RAN AND RAN AND
RAN.
NOT ONLY DID THEY AREN'T OUT OF
THE SCHOOL AND OFF OF THE SCHOOL
PROPERTY, THEY RAN DOWN THE
STREET, PAST THE FIREHOUSE, AND
JUST ULTIMATELY STOPPED ON A
MAN'S FRONT LAWN.
THAT MAN IS GENE ROSEN, WHO
LOOKED OUT OF HIS WINDOW AND HAD
NO IDEA WHAT HE WAS WITNESSING.
AND WHEN HE FOUND OUT, HE COULD
NOT BELIEVE THE STORY THAT WAS
COMING FROM THE MOUTHS OF THESE
BABES.
HE TOLD HIS STORY TO ERIN
BURNETT EXCLUSIVELY LAST NIGHT.
HAVE A LISTEN.
>> THEY WERE SITTING SO NICELY
BUT THEN I SAW A MAN IN A VERY
AGITATED WAY SAYING IT'S GOING
TO BE ALL RIGHT.
HE KEPT RAISING HIS VOICE.
I THOUGHT THAT WAS SO STRANGE.
AND I CAME TO THE CHILDREN AND
THEY WERE CRYING AND WAILING AND
MORTIFIED, AND THERE WAS A
SCHOOL BUS DRIVER WITH THEM.
AND I INVITED THEM INTO THE
HOUSE.
AND SHE SAID THAT AN INCIDENT AT
THE SCHOOL, I HAD NO IDEA WHAT
IT WAS.
>> THE CHILDREN, HOW DID THEY
FINE THE WORDS TO TELL YOU?
THEY TOLD YOU, RIGHT?
THE TEACHER HAD DIE GOOD THEY
START TALKING.
THE TWO BOYS MOSTLY TALKED.
AND THEY SAID, WE CAN'T GO BACK
TO THAT SCHOOL -- WE CAN'T --
>> WE CAN'T GO BACK.
>> OUR TEACHER -- OUR TEACHER'S
DEAD.
WHAT ARE WE GOING TO DO?
WE DON'T HAVE A TEACHER.
THEY WERE SO BRAVE AND THEY WERE
SO GOOD.
THEY -- I BROUGHT DOWN SOME TOYS
FROM MY GRANDSON'S TOY CHEST AND
I GAVE THEM SOME JUICE.
AND WE CALLED THEIR PARENTS.
THEY WERE VERY BRAVE.
AND VERY GOOD.
AND I WAS AMAZED.
I WAS -- I WAS ASTOUNDED AT WHAT
THEY WERE TELLING ME.
SOMETHING HAPPENED WITH ONE OF
THE BOYS.
OUT OF THIS GRIEF AND THIS
CARNAGE, AND HE STOPPED AND HE
BECAME VERY COMPOSED AND ALL OF
A SUDDEN HE STOPPED AND HE
LOOKED AT ME AND HE SAID, JUST
SAYING, YOUR HOUSE IS VERY
SMALL.
[ Woman ]
Ring. Ring.
Progresso.
I just finished a bowl of your
new Light Chicken Pot Pie Soup
and it's so rich
and creamy...
is it really 100 calories?
Let me put you on webcan...
...lean roasted chicken...
and a creamy broth
Mmm
I can still see you.
[ Male announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
>>> 14 DAYS AND COUNTING UNTIL
THE FISCAL CLIFF.
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER
PROPOSED LETTING TAX RATESEN
CREASE FOR ONLY THOSE MAKING
MORE THAN $1 MILLION A YEAR.
IT IS WHAT HE CALLS HIS PLAN B.
THE WHITE HOUSE SAYS ITS PLAN IS
BETTER AND IT IS ACTUALLY MORE
FAIR.
THE WHITE HOUSE PLAN CALLS FOR A
TAX INCREASE ON EARNINGS ABOVE
$400,000 A YEAR.
THAT'S A CONCESSION FROM
PRESIDENT OBAMA WHO ORIGINALLY
WANTED TAXES TO GO UP ON
ANYTHING ABOVE $250,000 A YEAR.
THE PRESIDENT'S OFFER ALSO CALLS
FOR $1.2 TRILLION IN SPENDING
CUTS INCLUDING THOSE ON SOCIAL
AND DEFENSE PROGRAMS.
HE WANTS A TWO-YEAR EXTENSION ON
BEING ABLE TO RAISE THE NATIONAL
DEBT CEILINGS.
REPUBLICANS NOT THRILLED WITH
THE WHITE HOUSE'S LATEST OFFER.
DANA BASH FOLLOWING THE BACK AND
FORTH HERE.
WE KNOW THAT BOTH SIDES SEEM TO
BE GIVING A BIT, RIGHT?
YOU'VE GOT THE PRESIDENT GOING
FROM $250,000 TO $400,000 AS A
THRESHOLD FOR INCREASING TAXES
AND THE REPUBLICANS PUSHING THIS
PLAN B HERE.
WHERE DO THEY MEET?
WHERE DO YOU SUPPOSE THEY MEET?
>> Reporter: BOY, IF I COULD
ANSWER THAT QUESTION WE WOULD BE
ABLE TO GO HOME.
LOOK, THIS IS -- THIS IS -- THIS
IS JUST MORE AGGRESSIVE YOU KNOW
KIND OF TO-ING AND FRO-ING WHEN
IT COMES TO THE HOUSE SPEAKER'S
STRATEGY HERE AND THE REPUBLICAN
STRATEGY.
YOU LAID OUT WELL WHAT THE WHITE
HOUSE OFFER WAS LAST NIGHT WHEN
THE PRESIDENT AND THE SPEAKER
MET IN PERSON AT THE WHITE
HOUSE.
BUT AFTER THAT, THE SPEAKER
CONCLUDED THAT HIS NEXT MOVE
WOULD BE THIS, THIS PLAN B,
BECAUSE HE FEELS THAT WHAT THE
PRESIDENT IS OFFER, NOT SO MUCH
IN THE WAY OF TAX BUT WAS
SPENDING CUTS IS NOT ENOUGH.
THAT HE'S NOT COMING DOWN --
GOING HIGH ENOUGH, RATHER, ON
SPENDING CUTS.
WITH THE HOUSE SPEAKER SAYING,
AS YOU SEE ON THE SCREEN, HE'S
GOING TO TRY TO PUSH LEGISLATION
THIS THURSDAY TO EXTEND TAX CUTS
FOR THOSE MAKING UP TO $1
MILLION SO THAT NOT EVERYBODY'S
TAXES WILL GO UP.
LISTEN TO HOW HE DESCRIBED IT TO
REPORTERS.
>> EVERY INCOME TAX FILER IN
AMERICA IS GOING TO PAY A HIGHER
RATE JANUARY 1st UNLESS CONGRESS
ACTS.
SO I BELIEVE IT'S IMPORTANT THAT
WE PROTECT AS MANY AMERICAN
TAXPAYERS AS WE CAN.
AND OUR PLAN B WOULD PROTECT
AMERICAN TAXPAYERS WHO MAKE $1
MILLION OR LESS AND HAVE ALL OF
THEIR CURRENT RATES EXTENDED.
>> Reporter: NOW, WHAT ARE THE
DEMOCRATS SAYING TO THIS?
THEY DON'T THINK A LOT OF IT.
THE WHITE HOUSE FLATLY REJECTED
IT.
DEMOCRATS WE'RE TALKING TO ON
THE HILL SAY IT'S LAUGHABLE.
ONE SENIOR DEMOCRATIC
CONGRESSMAN I TALKED TO SAID
THAT IT'S MORE OF A PUNCH LINE
INSTEAD OF A COMPROMISE BECAUSE
THEY FEEL THAT WHEN YOU LOOK AT
THE BIG PICTURE TALKS BETWEEN
THE PRESIDENT AND THE SPEAKER
THEY'RE FURTHER ALONG THAN THE
SPEAKER WILL GIVE THE PRESIDENT
CREDIT FOR FOR GIVING IN ON
TAXES, FOR GIVING ON WHAT HE
CAMPAIGNED ON, AS YOU WELL KNOW
FOR FIVE YEARS, WHICH IS RAISING
TAX RATES FOR PEOPLE MAKING
$250,000 OR MORE.
SO WE ARE DEFINITELY STILL IN
THE BACK AND FORTH PHASE.
THIS IS CLEARLY A NEGOTIATING
TACTIC BY THE SPEAKER TO TRY TO
PUSH THE PRESIDENT TO GIVE MORE
ON SPENDING CUTS AND TO AGREE TO
LESS WHEN IT COMES TO TAX
REVENUE.
>> READING THE TEA LEAVES HERE
IT DOES SEEM APPARENT THAT THIS
IS SOMEWHAT OF A TACTIC, THE
NEGOTIATION PROCESS TO GET
THROUGHOUT AND PUT FORWARD THE
PLAN B, BOTH MEN ARE STILL
TALKING.
THEY ARE STILL COMMUNICATING.
IS THAT A GOOD SIGN?
DOES THAT INDICATE THERE'S MORE
POSTURING, PUBLIC POSTURING
GOING ON HERE THAN WHAT WE'RE
SEEING BEHIND THE SCENES?
>> Reporter: WE HOPE SO.
WE DON'T HAVE ANY CONFIRMATION
THAT THE TWO MEN HAVE SPOKEN
TODAY.
WE KNOW THEY SPOKE LAST NIGHT
WHEN THE SPEAKERE64)Ñ TOLD THE
PRESIDENT HE WAS GOING FORWARD
ON PLAN B.
AS PART OF THE ANNOUNCEMENT THE
SPEAKER TOLD HIS COLLEAGUES
PRIVATELY AND RIGHT AFTERWARDS
THIS MORNING THAT HE IS GOING TO
CONTINUE TO TALK TO THE
PRESIDENT.
BUT THAT'S SORT OF ONE SIDE OF
THIS.
THIS IS THE REPUBLICAN SIDE
WHERE IT'S DIFFICULT FOR HIM TO
SELL THIS OVERALL, ABOUT $2
TRILLION PLAN THAT IS NOT HIGH
ENOUGH IN SPENDING CUTS BUT
THERE'S A DEMOCRATIC SIDE, TOO.
I'M TOLD DEMOCRATS ARE NOT HAPPY
WITH THE CONCESSIONS THAT THE
PRESIDENT'S MADE, SPECIFICALLY
ON THE IDEA OF PEOPLE --
EFFECTIVELY PEOPLE'S SOCIAL
SECURITY CHECKS BEING SMALLER AS
PART OF A TECHNICAL CHANGE.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> KIDNAPPED IN SYRIA.
HOW A NEWS CORRESPONDENT AND HIS
CREW WERE RESCUED AND RELEASED
AFTER HELD CAPTIVE FOR FIVE
THOMAS SARGENT.
NOBEL LAUREATE
IN ECONOMICS,
AND ONE OF THE MOST CITED
ECONOMISTS IN THE WORLD.
PROFESSOR SARGENT,
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT CD RATES WILL
BE IN TWO YEARS?
NO.
IF HE CAN'T, NO ONE CAN.
THAT'S WHY ALLY HAS
A RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
ALLY BANK.
YOUR MONEY NEEDS AN ALLY.
>>> KIDNAPPED, BLINDFOLDED,
THREATENED FOR FIVE DAYS.
RICHARD ENGEL AND HIS CREW
CAPTURED LAST THURSDAY AFTER
CROSSING INTO NORTHWEST SYRIA
FROM TURKEY.
ENGEL SAYS THEY WERE NOT
PHYSICALLY HARMED BUT SUFFERED
PSYCHOLOGICAL TORTURE AT HAND OF
THEIR CAPTORS.
HE TOLD THE "TODAY" SHOW HOW
THEY WERE FINALLY SET FREE.
>> AT THE END OF THIS WE WERE
BEING MOVED TO YET ANOTHER
LOCATION IN THE -- AROUND 11:00
LAST NIGHT, LOCAL TIME, AND AS
WE WERE MOVING ALONG THE ROAD,
THE KIDNAPPERS CAME ACROSS A
REBEL CHECKPOINT, SOMETHING THEY
HADN'T EXPECTED.
WE WERE IN THE BACK OF WHAT YOU
THINK OF AS A MINIVAN.
AS WE ARE DRIVING ALONG THE
ROAD, THE KIDNAPPERS SAW THIS
CHECKPOINT, STARTED A GUNFIGHT
WITH IT, TWO OF THE KIDNAPPERS
WERE KILLED.
WE CLIMBED OUT OF THE VEHICLE
AND THE REBELS TOOK US.
WE SPENT THE NIGHT WITH THEM.
WE DIDN'T GET MUCH SLEEP.
>> NONE OF THE NBC CREW WAS
HARMED.
WE ARE SO GLAD THAT THEY ARE
SAFE.
PAULA BROADWELL WON'T BE CHARGED
FOR CYBERSTOCKING.
IT WAS BROADWELL'S AFFAIR WITH
THE FORMER CIA CHIEF DAVID
PATREAUS THAT LET TO HIS
RESIGNATION BUT HER ANONYMOUS
E-MAILS LED TO THE FBI
INVESTIGATION.
THE U.S. TORNATTORNEY'S OFFICE
DECIDED NOT TO PURSUE A FEDERAL
CASE.
>>> PEOPLE REMEMBERING DANIEL
INOUE, DIED YESTERDAY OF
RESPIRATORY COMPLICATIONS IN
WASHINGTON, D.C.
A WORLD WAR II SVETERAN WHO
RECEIVED THE MEDAL OF HONOR.
THE LONGEST SERVING MEMBER OF
THE SENATE AND THE MEMBER OF THE
WATERGATE COMMITTEE THAT
RESULTED IN THE RESIGNATION OF
PRESIDENT NIXON.
HE WAS 88 YEARS OLD.
ASHLEIGH?
>> THERE IS SOMETHING THAT WE
WERE CONSIDERING A BRIGHT SPOT
TO REPORT FROM HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
AND THAT IS THAT -- PARDON ME --
THAT IS THAT AMID ALL OF THE
SADNESS, THESE DOGS HAVE SHOWN
UP TO HELP.
THEY ARE CALLED COMFORT DOGS AND
THEY HAVE DONE SO MUCH GOOD IN A
SHORT PERIOD OF TIME.
WE'RE GOING TO INTRODUCE YOU TO
THEM AND TELL YOU EXACTLY WHAT
THEY'VE BEEN UP TO, NEXT.
HEY, LOOK!
A SHOOTING STAR!
MAKE A WISH!
I WISH WE COULD
LIE HERE FOREVER.
I WISH THIS TEST DRIVE WAS OVER,
SO WE COULD HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
TEST DRIVE!
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A JETTA.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN,
$0 DUE AT SIGNING, $0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
>>> YOU KNOW, THERE HAVE BEEN A
COUPLE OF MOMENTS IN THE MIDDLE
OF THIS TERRIBLE SCHOOL SHOOTING
TRAGEDY WHERE WE HAVE BEEN ABLE
TO SHUT OUT THE SADNESS, EVEN IF
ONLY FOR JUST A LITTLE BIT.
BUT IN NEWTOWN, SEVERAL GOLDEN
RETRIEVERS HAVE BEEN HELPING TO
EASE THE PAIN.
THEY'RE CALLED COMFORT DOGS.
AND THEY, ALONG WITH THEIR HUMAN
HANDLERS, CAME HERE EN MASSE.
THEY TRAVELED TO CONNECTICUT,
ALL THE WAY FROM THE CHICAGO
AREA, AND THEIR MISSION WAS TO
HELP THE PEOPLE HERE WHO ARE
GRIEVING IN THE AFTERMATH OF
WHAT HAPPENED INSIDE THAT
SCHOOL.
THE PRESIDENT OF THE
ORGANIZATION THAT RUNS THE
PROGRAM TALKED TO OUR GARY
TUCHMAN.
>> TO SOME PEOPLE, WE HAVE SEEN
THIS WITH CHILDREN, IT BRINGS A
SENSE OF CALMNESS IN A TIME OF
CONFUSION FOR THEM DURING THIS
PERIOD.
TO SOME IT HELPS THEM PROCESS
THEIR GRIEF.
THEY'LL START CRYING AND THEY'LL
HUG THE DOG.
AND TO SOME CHILDREN, THEY'LL
COME UP SAD AND WALK AWAY HAPPY.
>> Reporter: DO YOU KNOW LUTHER
IS INCAPABLE OF BEING MEAN?
LUTHER IS A FRIENDLY DOG.
>> CADEN LOVES DOGS.
>> Reporter: WHERE ELSE HAVE
YOUR DOGS BEEN, WHAT OTHER
DISASTERS?
>> A MONTH AGO WHEN SANDY HIT,
WE WERE OUT IN NEW YORK AND NEW
JERSEY.
WE HAVE BEEN IN INDIANA WITH THE
FLOODINGS.
WE HAD DOGS IN JOPLIN, MISSOURI.
>> COME HERE, THIS IS LUTHER.
HE'S A COMFORT DOG.
YOU CAN PET HIM.
IT SAYS HERE, PLEASE PET ME.
>> Reporter: HOW DO YOU FEEL
WHEN YOU SEE A CHILD COME UP TO
ONE OF YOUR DOGS WHO HAS BEEN IN
THIS KIND OF SITUATION AND HAVE
A BIG SMILE ON THEIR FACE?
>> TEARS.
THEY SMILE, I CRY.
>> LIKE I SAID, SMILE IN THE
MIDST OF SUCH SADNESS.
AND IT IS SO WELCOME, THE
COMFORT DOG INITIATIVE, BY THE
WAY, WAS STARTED BACK IN 2008.
SADLY TO REPORT AFTER FIVE
COLLEGE STUDENTS DIED IN A MASS
SHOOTING IN ILLINOIS.
BUT, SUZANNE, WHAT A DIFFERENCE
THOSE DOGS HAVE BEEN ABLE TO
MAKE, EVEN IF ONLY FOR JUST A
SHORT MOMENT.
>> SO NICE TO SEE, YOU KNOW,
LIKE YOU GET ALL HAPPY AND
EXCITED JUST TO SEE THE DOG, THE
TAIL WAGGING AND, JUST, LIKE A
FRIENDLY FACE THERE.
WELL, THANK YOU, ASHLEIGH.
APPRECIATE THAT.
>>> ALSO, THE VOICE GETTING IN
ON PAYING TRIBUTE TO THE
STUDENTS AND THOSE WHO WERE
KILLED IN CONNECTICUT.
JUST WATCH.
♪ I HEARD THERE WAS
A SECRET CODE ♪
♪ THAT DAVID PLAYED
AND IT PLEASED THE LORD ♪
♪ BUT YOU DON'T
REALLY CARE FOR MUSIC
DO YOU ♪
>> LAST NIGHT'S SHOW OPENED WITH
THE CONTESTANTS, JUDGES SINGING
"HALLELUJAH" AND HOLDING UP
CARDS WITH THE NAME OF EACH
VICTIM.
IT IS JUST THE LATEST EXAMPLE OF
HOW EVERYBODY HAS COME TOGETHER
ACROSS THE COUNTRY AROUND THOSE
VICTIMS.
OVER THE WEEKEND, "SATURDAY
NIGHT LIVE" STARTED WITH A
CHILDREN'S CHOIR SINGING INSTEAD
OF THE USUAL MONOLOGUE.
OUR SPECIAL COVERAGE CONTINUES
AFTER THIS.
♪ HALLELUJAH
HALLELUJAH ♪
pportunity
in today's challenging
environment.
Unless you have the right
perspective.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
has the vision
and experience to look beyond
the obvious.
We'll uncover opportunities,
find hidden risk,
and make success a reality.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
but with ADVAIR,
I'm breathing better.
So now I can be in
the scene.
ADVAIR is
clinically proven to help
significantly improve
lung function.
Unlike most COPD medications,
ADVAIR contains both an
anti-inflammatory
and a
long-acting bronchodilator
working together to help improve
your lung function all day.
ADVAIR won't
replace fast-acting inhalers
for sudden symptoms
and should not be used more
than twice a day.
People with
COPD taking ADVAIR
may have a higher chance
of pneumonia.
ADVAIR may increase your
risk of osteoporosis
and some eye problems.
Tell your doctor
if you have a heart condition
or high blood pressure before
taking ADVAIR.
If you're still
having difficulty breathing,
ask your doctor if including
ADVAIR could help
improve your lung function.
Get your
first full
prescription
free
and save
on refills
at
ADVAIRcopd.com.
>>> ONE OF THE FIRST THINGS
YOU'LL NOTICE AS YOU DRIVE INTO
THIS BEAUTIFUL TOWN OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, IS SOME OF THE OLD
BUILDINGS AND THE LOVELY GENTLY
ROLLING HILLSIDE AND THEN THIS
EXTRAORDINARY TRAFFIC.
THE SCHOOL BUSES ARE NOW ROLLING
ONCE AGAIN AS THESE KIDS GET
READY TO HEAD BACK TO SCHOOL IN
THE NEWTOWN DISTRICT TODAY.
IT IS NOT NORMALLY LIKE THIS.
THE TRAFFIC IS COMPROMISED OF
PEOPLE FROM SURROUNDING
COUNTIES, CONTRACTORS WHO ARE
COMING IN TO HELP WITH THIS
EMERGENCY, MAYBE REBUILDING IN
SOME OF THE SCHOOLS, ET CETERA.
AND THEN ALSO AN ENORMOUS NUMBER
OF MEDIA.
ANOTHER THING YOU NOTICE AS YOU
COME INTO TOWN, RIGHT AWAY ON
THE LEFT-HAND SIDE IS THIS
MAKESHIFT MEMORIAL THAT SPRUNG
UP SEVERAL DAYS AGO AND IS
GROWING EXPONENTIALLY.
PEOPLE BRINGING TEDDY BEARS AND
CANDLES AND ART WORK AND
MESSAGES AND ORIGAMI AND FLOWERS
AND YOU NAME IT.
JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING.
YOU SEE A LOT OF PEOPLE WITH
TEARS AS THEY DROP OFF WHAT THEY
BROUGHT.
OBVIOUSLY SOME OF THE TRAFFIC,
PEOPLE FROM SURROUNDING
COMMUNITIES.
THE NEXT THING YOU NOTICE IS
THIS, ALL OF THIS MEDIA.
PEOPLE HAVE COME FROM ALL OVER
THE WORLD TO COVER THIS STORY.
AND THEY ARE SET UP RIGHT IN THE
TOWN SQUARE, RIGHT IN THE CENTER
OF TOWN, A PLACE THAT IS NOT
USED TO SEEING SATELLITE TRUCKS
AND THIS KIND OF MEDIA
ATTENTION.
AND, BOY, ARE THEY GETTING USED
TO IT NOW.
ANOTHER THING THAT YOU'LL FIND
AMIDST ALL THE TRAFFIC, TAKE A
LOOK UP HERE, POLICE AND ORANGE
CONES AND ROAD CLOSED SIGNS,
THAT IS THE ROAD THAT LEADS UP
TO THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
THEY ARE OBVIOUSLY LIMITING MOST
OF THE TRAFFIC, NOT ALLOWED TO
GO UP THERE AT THIS TIME.
THAT'S THE OTHER AREA WHERE
THERE IS A MASSIVE, MASSIVE
MEMORIAL.
I SHOWED THAT TO YOU YESTERDAY.
BUT ONE OF THE THINGS THAT WE DO
HEAR FROM PEOPLE, WHILE
EVERYBODY AROUND THE COUNTRY AND
AROUND THE WORLD WANTS TO SHARE
AND WANTS TO KNOW AND WANTS TO
BE A PART OF THIS, THIS
GRIEVING, AND THEY'RE DOING THAT
THROUGH US, AND THE WINDOW WE
PROVIDE, THE PEOPLE WHO LIVE
HERE REALLY WOULD LIKE US TO
LEAVE.
THEY WANT TO RETURN TO SOME KIND
OF NORMALCY AND THAT BEGS THAT