PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS.
AND EVERYONE LIKES 50% MORE...
[ Midwestern/Chicago accent ]
CHEDDAR! YEAH!
50 PERCENT MORE
[yodeling] YODEL-AY-EE-OO.
50% MORE FLASH.
[ Southern accent ]
50 PERCENT MORE TATERS.
THAT'S WHERE TOTS COME FROM.
[ Male Announcer ] THE
Capital One Cash Rewards Card
GIVES YOU 1% CASH BACK
ON EVERY PURCHASE
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS
ON THE CASH YOU EARN.
IT'S THE CARD FOR PEOPLE
WHO LIKE MORE CASH.
50% MORE SPY STUFF.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
THIS CAR IS TOO SMALL.
>>> WHEN WE FIRST ARRIVED THERE,
THERE WAS NOT A LOT OF SECURITY
TO GUARD.
AND THERE WERE THREE CHILDREN
THAT CAME OUT, ONE OF THEM WAS,
HAD A VERY BLOODY FACE.
IT WAS A VERY VIOLENT SCENE.
AND THERE WERE TWO OTHER ONES
THAT THEY WERE, YOU KNOW, THEY
WERE IN THE ARMS OF A STATE
TROOPER.
THEY DID NOT MOVE.
THEIR FACE WAS VERY PALE.
IT WAS VERY TRAGIC.
>> Reporter: WELCOME BACK,
EVERYBODY.
YOU'RE WATCHING OUR SPECIAL
COVERAGE OF THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SHOOTING THAT
HAPPENED 90 MINUTES NORTH OF NEW
YORK CITY.
I WANT TO UPDATE YOU ON THE VERY
LATEST WE KNOW.
A COUPLE THINGS WE ARE WAITING
FOR, WE ARE EXPECTING A PRESS
CONFERENCE FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT.
THEY HAVE BEEN DOING THEM
REGULARLY.
THEY ARE NOW 90 MINUTES DELAYED
OR SO ON THAT.
WE ARE WAITING TO HEAR THE VERY
LATEST INSIDE THAT SCENE BECAUSE
THEY HAVE OBVIOUSLY CLOSED DOWN
THAT SCENE.
AND IT'S BEING TREATED AS A
CRIME SCENE.
THEY HAVE BEEN TRYING TO PROCESS
THE CRIME SCENE AS THE LAST
THING THEY HAVE TOLD US.
WE ARE WAITING ON THE UPDATE OF
THAT.
IT IS 20 CHILDREN BETWEEN THE
AGES OF 5 AND 10 KILLED IN THIS
TERRIBLE TRAGEDY AS WELL AS SIX
ADULTS AT THE SCHOOL.
INCLUDING THE SCHOOL'S PRINCIPAL
AND SKY PSYCHOLOGIST.
THE SUSPECT IS 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM
LANZA.
SOURCES SAY HE WAS ARMED WITH
THREE GUNS, WORE FATIGUES AND
HAD A MILITARY VEST ON.
HE GOT THE GUNS FROM HIS MOTHER.
ALL FIVE GUNS WERE REGISTERED TO
HER.
AND SHE WAS FOUND DEAD IN HER
HOME NOT FAR FROM WHERE WE ARE
RIGHT NOW.
PARENTS AND TEACHERS, I THINK IT
IS FAIR TO SAY THE ENTIRE NATION
IS STRUGGLING WITH HOW TO REALLY
UNDERSTAND HOW A GUNMAN COULD
OPEN FIRE ON A BUNCH OF SMALL
CHILDREN AT AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
SO WE WANTED TO HAVE A
CONVERSATION ABOUT HOW TO HAVE
THAT CONVERSATION.
DR. ERIC FISHER IS A LICENSED
CLINICAL PSYCHOLOGIST, AN EXPERT
ON POST-TRAUMATIC STRESS
DISORDER.
DR. FISHER, I APPRECIATE YOU
TALKING TO US.
JUST A FEW MOMENTS AGO I TALKED
TO A FIRST AND THIRD GRADER.
AND ONE OF THE THINGS THEY SAID
TO ME IS THEY DON'T REALLY KNOW
WHAT TO DO.
THEY HAVE BEEN LETTING THE KIDS
DICTATE HOW MUCH THEY TALK OR
HOW MUCH NOT TO TALK, BUT NOW
THAT THEY KNOW SOME OF THEIR
FIRST GRADERS' BEST FRIENDS HAVE
BEEN MASSACRED, THEY JUST DON'T
KNOW WHAT TO DO.
WHAT WOULD YOU ADVISE THEM TO
DO?
>> WELL, I THINK YOU DO IN SOME
WAYS LET YOUR CHILD TAKE THE
LEAD AND ASK THEM WHAT THEY KNOW
AND WHAT THEY ARE AWARE OF.
WHEN PEOPLE EXPERIENCE TRAUMA,
IT IS NOT OFTEN STORED IN THE
VERBAL CENTERS OF THE BRAIN BUT
THE NON-VERBAL CENTER OF THE
BRAIN.
AS KIDS WORK THIS THROUGH, THEY
COULD HAVE A LOT OF EMOTION BUT
NOT HAVE WORDS.
A LOT OF TIMES WE HAVE EMOTIONS
BEFORE WE HAVE WORDS.
AND WE HAVE TO SEE THAT
EVERYBODY WORKS THROUGH THEIR
GRIEF AND EMOTION DIFFERENTLY.
I ENCOURAGE PEOPLE TO DRAW, TO
WRITE, TO COLOR, TO PAINT, TO
SING THROUGH THEIR HEALING
PROCESS.
AT THIS TIME, THOUGH, ANYBODY
WHOSE BEEN IN THIS EXPERIENCE IS
GOING TO NEED SOME PROFESSIONAL
HELP AND SUPPORT.
THAT'S JUST AN ABSOLUTE.
SO THE SOONER THEY CAN GET TO
SOMEBODY AND CONSULT WITH PEOPLE
WHO ARE EXPERTS AND
PROFESSIONALS IN THE AREA, THE
BETTER THEY WILL BE IN THE LONG
RUN.
ALSO AS PARENTS, MAKE SURE
YOU'RE TAKING CARE OF
YOURSELVES, TOO.
IF YOUR KIDS SEE YOU WORN AND
HAVING A DIFFICULT TIME, SOME OF
THAT IS GOING TO BE OKAY BECAUSE
THEY WILL SEE THIS IS A HUMAN
EXPERIENCE.
HOWEVER, IT IS IMPORTANT THAT
YOU HAVE AN OUTLET AS A PARENT
TO BE THERE TO SUPPORT YOUR KIDS
AND MAKE SURE YOU'RE CONSULTING
A PROFESSIONAL IF YOU NEED THAT.
TOO.
>> Reporter: I WANT TO BRING IN
DR. SANJAY GUPTA.
UR CHIEF MEDICAL CORRESPONDENT.
YOU HAVE DONE A LOT OF WORK IN
MOST TRAUMATIC STRESS.
ARE CHILDREN'S BRAINS CAPABLE OF
OVERCOMING THIS MORE EASILY THAN
ADULTS OR DO YOU FIND THE
OPPOSITE, DOES IT AFFECT THEM
FOR THE REST OF THEIR LIVES?
>> THEY BOTH CAN BE AFFECTED BY
POST-TRAUMATIC STRESS DISORDER,
BUT KIDS ARE RESILIENT.
THE SAME SORT OF EPISODES ARE
SORT LIVED.
SO JUST AS YOUR GUEST WAS
SAYING, A LOT OF TIMES IT COULD
BE VERY SUBTLE THINGS.
A LITTLE BIT OF REGRESSION, FOR
EXAMPLE, IN TERMS OF DEVELOPMENT
AND TEMPER TANTRUMS.
SOMETHING THAT SEEMS UNUSUAL,
BUT OFTENTIMES IT COULD BE MORE
SHORT-LIVED.
I SAW SOMETHING VERY
INTERESTING, SOLEDAD, AND WE
TALKED ABOUT THIS BEFORE.
SLEEP CAN OFTENTIMES BE ONE OF
THE FIRST BIG -- SLEEP CAN BE A
VERY POWERFUL PREDICTOR OVERALL
OF HOW SOMEONE COPES IN THE
LONG-TERM.
SO EVEN LAST NIGHT, TONIGHT,
PARENTS WATCHING AND MAKING SURE
THEIR KIDS ARE GETTING SLEEP.
I KNOW IT SOUNDS LIKE A SIMPLE
THING, BUT IF YOU LOOK AT THE
STUDY, IT'S A POWERFUL PREDICTOR
HOW THEY WILL COPE IN THE LONG
RUNG.
>> Reporter: I WANT TO GO BACK
TO ERIK FISHER, FOR PEOPLE WHO
WERE NOT HERE AND WHOSE CHILDREN
DID NOT GO THROUGH THE TRAUMA,
AND YET I THINK AS ANY PARENT
WATCHING THE STORY UNFOLD FROM
AROUND THE COUNTRY, WE ARE
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT HOW DO I
TELL MY CHILD HONESTLY THEY WILL
BE SAFE IN SCHOOL WHEN I CANNOT
HONESTLY SAY THAT.
AND AS YOU KNOW THEY KNOW WHEN
YOU'RE LYING AND TRYING NOT TO
LIE BUT YOU ALSO WANT TO GIVE
THEM REASSURANCE.
WHAT DO YOU DO?
>> I'M CAREFUL TO NOT MAKE
PROMISES.
I NEVER TELL MY 7-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHTER I PROMISE BECAUSE WE
CANNOT MAKE PROMISES OVER THINGS
WE DO NOT CONTROL.
I REALLY TRY TO SAY THIS IS WHAT
WE ARE DOING AND THESE ARE THE
PLANS I HAVE.
MAKE SURE YOU KNOW YOU HAVE AN
EMERGENCY PLAN IF YOU GET
SEPARATED, WHAT'S YOUR EMERGENCY
CALL AND WHERE'S A SAFE PLACE TO
GO THAT'S A MEETING PLACE OR
THINGS LIKE THAT.
THOSE ARE THINGS IMPORTANT TO
HAVE IN PLACE.
BECAUSE THE MORE PEOPLE FEEL
LIKE THEY HAVE A PLAN, THE LESS
STRESS THAT OCCURS IN A
SITUATION IN THE LONG-TERM
STRESS.
DR. GUPTA MADE A GREAT POINT
ABOUT WATCHING SLEEP BECAUSE OF
THE STRESS HORMONES SECRETED
WHEN SLEEP DEPRIVED BUT YOU ARE
NOT JUST LOOKING HOW KIDS
RESPOND FOR THE NEXT MONTH OR
YEAR, BUT IN THE WORK OF PEOPLE
WITH TRAUMAS AS CHILDREN, WE ARE
TALKING ABOUT THE NEXT 20 YEARS.
EVEN IN THESE EVENTS, I HAVE HAD
TO CONSULT WITH CLIENTS TO SAY
TURN OFF THE TV.
DON'T WATCH IT AS THEY BRING UP
HUGE TRIGGERS FOR POST-TRAUMATIC
STRESS.
>> Reporter: IT IS SO
INTERESTING TO HEAR THE
DESCRIPTIONS OF THE TEACHERS SO
CLEARLY HEROES.
HAVING THE CHILDREN HIDE IN
CUBBIES AND TRY TO PROTECT THEM
IN A WAY THAT WITH A GUNMAN
ROAMING AROUND, THEY CAN'T
REALLY PROTECT THEM IN DOING
THEIR ALL AND BEING ORGANIZED
AND BRINGING THEM TO THE
FIREHOUSE.
THAT'S AMAZING.
IS THAT A WAY TO FOCUS?
IT BREAKS MY HEART, IT IS SO
UPSETTING, BUT AT THE SAME TIME
IT FEELS LIKE ONE POSITIVE THING
IN THIS HORRIBLE THING IS PEOPLE
WERE TRULY HEROIC.
>> IT IS TOUGH TO TALK ABOUT,
BUT THE WHOLE NOTION OF
EMPOWERING YOURSELF IN SOME WAY.
IN A SITUATION WHERE YOU SEEM TO
HAVE LOST COMPLETE CONTROL.
YOU HAVE NO LONGER TO DO
ANYTHING ALL TO EMPOWER YOURSELF
OR THE PEOPLE AROUND YOU.
IT MAY SEEM LIKE SMALL THINGS,
JUST SINGING SONGS TO THE
CHILDREN, HIDING IN CLOSETS, AND
NOT EVEN BEING SURE THOSE WILL
HAVE A SIGNIFICANT IMPACT IN
TERMS OF PREVENTING THE HORROR,
BUT THAT EMPOWERMENT GOES A LONG
WAY AS SAYING, CONTROL YOUR OWN
FEELINGS BEFORE CONTROLLING
EVERY ONE'S FEELINGS.
YOU HAVE BEEN HEARING THESE
STORIES ALL DAY.
>> Reporter: LET ME ASK YOU A
QUESTION, SANJAY, ABOUT WHAT A
FAMILY MEMBER OF THE SHOOTER,
ADAM LANZA TOLD INVESTIGATORS.
HE SAID THAT ADAM HADAUTISM.
MY NEPHEW IS AUTISTIC AND I HAVE
NEVER HEARD TO AUTISM BEING
LINKED TO THIS VIOLENT BEHAVIOR.
WE HAVE LINKED IT TO SMASZ
SHOOTINGS BEFORE BUT NOT AUTISM.
WHAT IS YOUR STUDY?
>> THERE ARE HARDLY ANY STUDIES
ON THIS, BUT THERE WERE A COUPLE
FROM A YEAR OR TWO AGO THA TO
SHOW THE LINK BETWEEN THIS AND
ANY KIND OF VIOLENT BEHAVIOR WAS
THE STUDIES DON'T BEAR THAT OUT.
VIOLENT OUTBURSTS LIKE ANY CHILD
OR YOUNG PERSON I HAVE ARE
THERE.
THERE ARE SOME STUDIES LOOKING
AT EMPATHY.
COULD THERE BE LIMITED EMPATHY?
BUT EVEN THE STUDIES ARE
LIMITED.
I WILL SAY, FOR EXAMPLE, THE
DIAGNOSIS OF ASPERGERS IS NOT A
DIAGNOSIS.
AS OF THIS YEAR THAT DIAGNOSIS
IS GONE.
SO I GUESS I WOULDN'T REACH TOO
MUCH INTO THAT.
>> Reporter: AS WE ARE WAITING
FOR INFORMATION TO COME TO US,
ERIK FISHER, THANK YOU FOR
JOINING US THIS MORNING WITH
YOUR INSIGHT.
AND SANJAY, I APPRECIATE YOUR
TIME.
WE ARE WAITING FOR THIS PRESS
CONFERENCE.
THERE ARE NOW, WHAT WOULD YOU
SAY, LIKE 100 CAMERAS AT LEAST
HERE LINED UP FOR THE STATE
POLICE AND THE NEWTOWN POLICE
OFFICIALS TO COME OUT AND UPDATE
US ON THE VERY LATEST THAT THEY
KNOW.
WE ALSO KNOW A LITTLE BIT MORE
DETAIL FROM THE LIBRARIAN AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
SHE SAYS THE KIDS AND THE TEEN
TEACHERS WERE PREPARED ON WHAT
THEY COULD OVERHEAR OVER THE
INTERCOM.
SHE TALKED A FEW MOMENTS AGO ON
WHAT SHE DID TO KEEP KIDS SAFE
DURING THE SHOOTING SPREE.
LISTEN.
>> EVERYBODY DOES WHAT THEY HAVE
TO DO WHEN CONFRONTED IN A
SITUATION LIKE THAT.
AND EVERYBODY THAT WE PRACTICED
IT, AND THEY KNEW WHAT TO DO,
AND YOU JUST THINK ABOUT
PROTECTING THE KIDS AND JUST
DOING THE RIGHT THING.
>> Reporter: HOW LONG DID YOU
PRACTICE THIS?
>> WE HAVE LOCKDOWN DRILLS.
I DON'T REMEMBER HOW MANY, BUT
THERE ARE RULES TO HAVE A
CERTAIN NUMBER A YEAR.
SO THE KIDS KNOW THE ROUTINE.
EVERYONE HAS A SPOT IN THE ROOM
WHERE THEY ARE SUPPOSED TO GO
TO.
>> Reporter: CAN YOU DESCRIBE
THAT SPACE FOR US?
>> IN THE LIBRARY IT IS BETWEEN
A COUPLE BOOKCASES WITH NO
WINDOWS.
WE WENT INTO A BACK STORAGE ROOM
AND LOCKED THE KIDS IN THERE.
>> Reporter: HOW CLOSE WERE YOU
THERE?
>> WE WERE LIKE THIS CLOSE
TOGETHER.
THERE WAS CRAYONS AND PAPER THE
STORAGE ROOM IN THE BACK.
AND WE TORE SOME UP AND GAVE
THEM CLIPBOARDS AND HAD THEM
COLOR AND DRAW PICTURES.
THERE WERE THREE OTHER ADULTS
WITH ME.
THEY WERE ASKING WHAT'S GOING
ON, WE SAID WE DON'T KNOW.
OUR JOB IS TO STAY QUIET.
IT COULD BE A DRILL OR MAY NOT.
>> Reporter: YOU DIDN'T KNOW AT
THAT POINT?
>> WE KNEW BECAUSE I CALLED THE
OFFICE AND SHE TOLD ME THERE WAS
A SHOOTER.
>> MY KIDS, FRIENDS OF THEIRS
HAVE LITTLE SISTERS OR BROTHERS
DEAD.
EVERYBODY IN TOWN KNOWS
EVERYBODY.
THERE'S NOT GOING TO BE ANYBODY
AFFECTED BY THIS.
IT IS AWFUL.
I'M JUST GLAD THEY WERE SAFE AND
THEY WERE WORRIED ABOUT ME
BECAUSE WE WERE IN LOCKDOWN AND
DIDN'T KNOW.
THE KIDS BACK HOME IN HIGH
SCHOOL WERE LEFT WATCHING IT ON
TV.
IT WAS PROBABLY REALLY DIFFICULT
FOR THEM.
>> Reporter: DID YOU KNOW THE
MOTHER?
>> NO.
SHE WAS NOT INTO PLAY THERE AS
FAR AS I KNOW.
>> Reporter: MANY PEOPLE WERE
SAYING HOW GREAT THE PRINCIPAL
WAS.
>> SHE WAS A PERSONAL FRIEND AND
A WONDERFUL MOTHER.
>> Reporter: JUST DEVASTATING
FOR PEOPLE TRYING TO MAKE SENSE
OF WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
A LOT OF PEOPLE STILL GRATEFUL
THEIR CHILDREN SURVIVED AND THEN
ALL THE PARENTS WHO ARE MOURNING
TODAY.
20 CHILDREN LOST THEIR LIVES IN
THIS TERRIBLE, TERRIBLE HORRIFIC
SHOOTING.
>> WE LOST A LOT OF BABIES TODAY
IN THIS TOWN.
AND THERE ARE A LOT OF VERY SAD
FAMILIES.
AND AS EVERYONE CAN THINK, YOU
NEVER THINK IT IS GOING TO
HAPPEN, BUT BASICALLY IT HAPPENS
ALL OVER THE WORLD AT THIS
POINT.
♪
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
>>> AS A COUNTRY WE HAVE BEEN
THROUGH THIS TOO MANY TIMES.
WHETHER IT IS A SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, A TEMPLE IN WISCONSIN,
A MOVIE THEATER IN AURORA OR A
STREET CORNER IN CHICAGO, THESE
NEIGHBORHOODS ARE OUR
NEIGHBORHOODS AND THESE CHILDREN
ARE OUR CHILDREN.
AND WE ARE GOING TO HAVE TO COME
TOGETHER TO TAKE ACTION TO
PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES AND
PREVENT THE POLITICS.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING.
WE ARE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
THIS MORNING.
WE ARE AWAITING A PRESS
CONFERENCE TO GET UNDERWAY.
THEY ARE GATHERED JUST TO MY
LEFT, BUT WE ARE WAITING FOR THE
FOLKS FROM THE STATE POLICE AND
ALSO THE LOCAL POLICE TO UPDATE
US ON THE VERY LATEST.
THE CRIME SCENE IS JUST A HALF
MILE THROUGH THAT WOODS.
THAT'S SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
AND, OF COURSE, IT WAS THE SIGHT
AND SCENE OF SO MUCH CHAOS.
WE WANT TO TALK A LITTLE BIT
ABOUT WHAT THE PRESIDENT SAID.
IT WAS VERY UNUSUAL TO SEE HIM
SO EMOTIONAL AND SO CHOKED UP AS
HE GAVE THAT BRIEF REMARK ABOUT
THE SHOOTING.
BRIANNA KIELER REPORTING FOR US
FROM THE WHITE HOUSE.
I HAVE TO SAY I HAVE NEVER SEEN
A SPEECH THAT HE COULDN'T ALMOST
GET THROUGH.
AND I THINK A LOT OF PEOPLE
WOULD SAY THE SAME THING.
>> Reporter: IT WAS A VERY
EMOTIONAL MOMENT FOR PRESIDENT
OBAMA, SOLEDAD.
SOMETHING CERTAINLY REMARKABLE,
BUT THERE WAS SOMETHING ELSE IN
HIS COMMENTS THAT WAS ALSO
REMARKABLE.
IF YOU'RE SOMEONE WHO LISTENS TO
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND YOU REALLY
PARSE EVERY WORD HE SAYS, AS SO
MANY OF US DO, HE TALKED ABOUT
HAVING MEANINGFUL ACTION.
THIS IS SIGNIFICANT.
BECAUSE WHITE HOUSE PRESS
SECRETARY JAY CARNEY WAS ASKED
YESTERDAY ABOUT WHAT MIGHT
HAPPEN IN THE WAKE OF THIS
TRAGEDY.
EVERY TIME, UNFORTUNATELY, THAT
THERE IS A SHOOTING LIKE THIS,
PEOPLE START ASKING ABOUT WHAT
KIND OF LEGISLATION MIGHT
CONGRESS BE ABLE TO ENABLE TO
ENACT TO STOP THIS FROM
HAPPENING.
A LOT OF TIMES THAT MEANS TO BE
GUN ADVOCATES SAYING SOMETHING
NEEDS TO BE DONE.
THIS HAS NOT BEEN A PRIORITY FOR
MR. OBAMA IN HIS FIRST TIME, BUT
LISTEN AGAIN TODAY AS HE SAID IT
IN HIS WEEKLY ADDRESS.
>> AS A NATION WE HAVE ENDURED
FAR TOO MANY OF THESE TRAGEDIES
IN THE LAST FEW YEARS.
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
A SHOPPING MALL IN OREGON, THE
HOUSE OF WORSHIP IN WISCONSIN,
THE MOVIE THEATER IN COLORADO,
COUNTLESS STREET CORNERS IN
PLACES LIKE CHICAGO AND
PHILADELPHIA.
ANY OF THESE NEIGHBORHOODS COULD
BE OUR OWN, SO WE HAVE TO COME
TOGETHER AND WE'LL HAVE TO MAKE
MEANINGFUL ACTION TO PREVENT
MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS FROM
HAPPENING.
REGARDLESS OF POLITICS.
>> Reporter: SO WHAT DOES THAT
MEAN, MEANINGFUL ACTION?
WE DON'T KNOW.
DOES THAT MEAN HE MAY TRY TO
PURSUE GUN CONTROL LEGISLATION?
HONESTLY, WE DON'T KNOW AT THIS
POINT, BUT I WILL TELL YOU,
SOLEDAD, THAT GUN CONTROL
ADVOCATES LOOK AT PRESIDENT
OBAMA'S RECORD ON GUN CONTROL
AND THEY SAY THAT IT'S DISMAL.
HE GOT AN "F" FROM THE BRADY
CAMPAIGN IN 2008 WHEN HE WAS
CAMPAIGNING AND MADE A PROMISE
TO PURSUE RENEWING THAT
SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPONS BAND THAT
EXPIRED IN 2004.
THAT NEVER CAME TO FRUITION.
IN JULY I WAS IN NEW ORLEANS AS
HE GAVE A SPEECH TO THE URBAN
LEAGUE WHERE HE TALKED ABOUT GUN
VIOLENCE AND HAVING A
CONVERSATION ABOUT IT, BUT IN AN
ELECTION YEAR NOTHING EVER
HAPPENED TO IT.
IT IS NOT REALLY AN APPETITE IN
CONGRESS AND TRADITIONALLY IT IS
REPUBLICANS WHO ARE MORE IN
FAVOR OF GUN
THERE ARE MANY DEMOCRATS WHO ARE
NOT IN FAVOR OF PURSUING NEW
GUN-CONTROL LEGISLATION
INCLUDING THE HEAD OF THE
SENATE, SENATE MAJORITY LEADER
HARRY REID.
IT'S REALLY INTERESTING TO
LISTEN TO HIS LANGUAGE AND
WONDER WHAT MIGHT COME OUT OF
THIS.
IT'S AN OPEN QUESTION AT THIS
POINT, SOLEDAD.
>> Reporter: YEAH, I THINK AN
OPEN QUESTION ON A LOT OF
FRONTS.
REPORTING FROM THE WHITE HOUSE,
THANK YOU.
WHAT EXACTLY DOES MEANINGFUL
ACTION MEAN?
IT'S WHAT THE PRESIDENT SAID IS
NEEDED TO STOP GUN VIOLENCE.
THE TRAGEDIES RAISE THE LEVEL OF
THE DEBATE ABOUT GUN CONTROL.
I WANT TO READ A COUPLE OF
STATEMENTS FOR YOU.
LET'S LOOK AT THOSE.
IF YOU CAN SCROLL UP.
THIS COMES FROM THE NATIONAL
RIFLE ASSOCIATION, "UNTIL THE
FACTS ARE THOROUGHLY KNOWN, THE
NRA HAS NO COMMENT."
THIS COMES FROM THE NATIONAL
SHOOTING SPORTS FOUNDATION.
ACTUALLY, BASED HERE.
THEY SAY THIS, CAN YOU SCROLL
DOWN AGAIN SO I TODAY THAT?
"OUR HEARTS GO OUT TO THE
FAMILIES OF THIS HORRIBLE
TRAGEDY IN OUR COMMUNITY.
OUT OF RESPECT FOR THE FAMILIES,
THE COMMUNITY AND THE ONGOING
POLICE INVESTIGATION, IT WOULD
BE INAPPROPRIATE TO COMMENT."
SO FROM BOTH OF THEM, PRETTY
MUCH GETTING A BIG RESOUNDING NO
COMMENT AT THIS POINT.
WANT TO GET TO CALIFORNIA
REPUBLICAN CONGRESSWOMAN MARY
BONO MACK.
NICE TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
WE'VE HAD AN OPPORTUNITY TO TALK
ABOUT A LOT OF THINGS THE LAST
YEAR ON MY MORNING PROGRAM.
YOU'RE A PARENT FIRST AND
FOREMOST.
WHAT'S YOUR RESPONSE TO WHAT HAS
UNFOLDED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT?
>> HI, SOLEDAD.
THUNDERSTORM WATCH FOR HAVING ME
HERE.
MY RESPONSE -- THANK YOU FOR
HAVING ME HERE.
MY RESPONSE IS THE SAME AS EVERY
AMERICAN IS HAVING NOW, THAT IS
A BONE-CHILLING SADNESS.
I THINK THAT WE ALL GRIEVE RIGHT
NOW.
I THINK THERE'S A PIECE OF EVERY
SINGLE PARENT RIGHT NOW WITH
THESE PARENTS AND THESE
FAMILIES.
AND YOU KNOW, YOU'VE DONE SUCH A
GREAT JOB ALREADY THIS MORNING
OF EXPLORING THE WHAT IFs AND
WHY NOT MY SCHOOL AND THANK GOD
IT'S NOT MY SCHOOL.
AND ALL OF THE PAIN AND
SUFFERING THAT WE'RE ALL FEELING
NOW.
AS WE WAIT FOR ANSWERS, WHY THIS
HORRIFIC THING HAPPENED, WHY WE
DECIDED -- HOW WE DECIDED AS A
DOWN MOVE FORWARD TO MAKE SURE
IT DOESN'T HAPPEN AGAIN.
>> Reporter: WHAT DO YOU THINK
THAT MEANS?
I'M GOING TO WARN YOU, WE'RE
WAITING FOR THIS PRESS
CONFERENCE.
WE'VE BEEN WAITING ALL MORNING.
I 1995 JUMP IN WHEN YOU'RE
TALKING AND JUST INTERRUPT FOR
THEIR START.
BUT THAT HASN'T HAPPENED YET.
SO WHAT DOES MEANINGFUL ACTION
MEAN?
WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE TO SEE?
YOU SUPPORT GUN RIGHTS IN THIS
COUNTRY.
YOU'RE A REPUBLICAN, AND I THINK
THAT'S A POSITION CONSISTENT
WITH MOST REPUBLICANS.
WHAT DOES MEANINGFUL ACTION,
THAT ACTUALLY STOPS THESE KINDS
OF SHOOTINGS, LOOK LIKE TO YOU?
>> FIRST OF ALL, I AM A
REPUBLICAN WHO HAS HAD
QUESTIONS, TOO, ABOUT A NUMBER
OF THE ISSUES THAT HAVE COME
BEFORE US ABOUT GUN RIGHTS AND
GUN CONTROL.
FOR EXAMPLE, COP KILLER BULLETS
OR, YOU KNOW, LARGE MAGAZINES.
I'VE ASKED THOSE QUESTIONS.
BUT WHERE I KEEP GETTING TO
REALLY QUICKLY IS THE MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUE.
I KEEP WONDERING WHY THESE
PEOPLE SNAP.
ESPECIALLY IN THIS INSTANCE,
THERE -- THESE CHILDREN WERE, AS
SOMEBODY SAID TO ME EARLIER,
THEY WERE ANGELS.
THEY WERE ABSOLUTELY
DEFENSELESS.
AND WHAT WOULD MAKE SOMEBODY
SNAP SO TERRIBLY TO DO SOMETHING
THIS HEINOUS?
SO THE QUESTION FOR ME IS NOT
JUST GUN RIGHTS BUT MENTAL
HEALTH.
I AGREE THAT I'VE NEVER HEARD
THIS ABOUT AUTISM.
I DON'T KNOW THAT THERE WOULD BE
A LINK THERE.
BUT I REALLY BELIEVE THAT THERE
ARE LINK T-- LINKS TO MENTAL
HEALTH.
WE NEED TO DISCUSS WHAT WE CAN
DO BETTER IN THE MENTAL HEALTH
SYSTEM.
>> MAYBE THE ANSWER THEN IS BOTH
-- I DON'T KNOW THAT YOU'RE
GOING TO GET A LOT OF PEOPLE WHO
ARE GOING TO BE AGAINST GIVING
PEOPLE MORE MENTAL HEALTH
COUNSELING, ET CETERA, ET
CETERA.
SO I WOULD AGREE COMPLETELY ON
THAT FRONT.
LET'S GO BACK TO GUN CONTROL.
WHAT DO YOU THINK COULD BE DONE
TO MAKE PEOPLE SAFE?
I MEAN, THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO
HAVE SAID, AND I THINK HONESTLY
HORRIBLY HAVE SAID THAT IF
PEOPLE WERE ARMED INSIDE THE
SCHOOL THEY WOULD HAVE BEEN ABLE
TO SHOOT THE SHOOTER.
DO YOU AGREE WITH THAT?
>> WELL, YES.
I MEAN, THAT IS ONE PORTION OF
IT I GUESS.
YOU KNOW, I THINK THOSE OF US
WHO FLY OFTEN KNOW THAT WE FEEL
SOME SORT OF CONSOLATION OR
SAFETY KNOWING THAT THERE MIGHT
BE AIR MARSHALS ON BOARD.
YOU WANT TO KNOW SOMETIMES IF
THERE'S SOMEBODY THERE WHO CAN
DEFEND YOU IN A SITUATION.
BUT YOU HAVE TO LOOK AT THESE
INDIVIDUALS AND TO RECOGNIZE
THEY GO TO GREAT LENGTHS TO HARM
OTHER PEOPLE.
WHAT LENGTHS ARE THEY GOING TO
GO TO IF GUNS AREN'T AT THEIR
DISPOSAL?
THEY'RE GOING TO GO TO THE NEXT
BEST THING WHETHER IT'S, YOU
KNOW, EXPLOSIVES OR PIPE BOMBS,
WHATEVER IT'S GOING TO BE.
I MEAN, I SHUDDER TO THINK.
BUT THESE PEOPLE ARE DERANGED OR
HAVE SNAPPED.
>> Reporter: ISN'T PART OF THE
ISSUE -- ISN'T PART OF THE ISSUE
THAT THERE'S EASY ACCESS?
WE DO KNOW THAT HIS MOTHER HAD
FIVE LEGALLY OBTAINED GUNS.
SHE WAS LICENSED FOR FIVE GUNS,
AT LEAST ONE OF THEM IS THIS
BUSH 223 -- BUSHMASTER RIFLE,
RIGHT?
A SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPON.
HE HAD EASY ACCESS TO THAT.
SO I FIND IT HARD WHEN PEOPLE
SAY, WELL, YOU KNOW, IF YOU
DIDN'T HAVE A GUN YOU COULD DO
SOMETHING ELSE.
IS THE ANSWER THEN ARMING MORE
PEOPLE?
THAT DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE TO
ME HONESTLY.
>> NO, BUT SOLEDAD, IT PROBABLY
DOESN'T.
BUT WE REALLY NEED TO HAVE A
ROBUST DISCUSSION THAT INCLUDES
ALL OF THIS.
THE TALKS ABOUT GUN CONTROL,
ACCESS TO WEAPONS, AND MENTAL
HEALTH.
AND WHAT IT ALL MEANS.
YOU KNOW, THESE VICTIMS AND
THESE FAMILIES REALLY DESERVE A
VERY THOROUGH DISCUSSION.
YOU KNOW, IT'S REALLY -- I THINK
WE ALWAYS WANT THE QUICK AND
EASY ANSWER.
AND THAT MAY OR MAY NOT BE GUN
CONTROL.
I DON'T KNOW.
RIGHT NOW I THINK -- I'M
GRIEVING TOO MUCH TO TRY TO
FIGURE IT OUT, YOU KNOW -- BUT
WE NEED A VERY THOROUGH --
>> Reporter: I DON'T KNOW THAT
PEOPLE WANT QUICK AND EASY
ANSWERS.
HONESTLY WITH ALL DUE RESPECT,
AND YOU AND I HAVE HAD MANY
CONVERSATIONS OVER THE PAST
YEAR.
WE TALK A LOT.
I THINK THERE'S ALWAYS A
TRAGEDY, WE ALL RUN OUT AND
COVER IT.
AND PEOPLE WATCH AT HOME, AND
THEY'RE BROKEN HEARTED.
WE GO ON THE NEXT DAY OR THREE
WEEKS LATER AS IF, WELL, THAT'S
DONE.
THEN WE REVISIT THE ISSUE AGAIN
AT THE NEXT TRAGEDY.
I GUARANTEE THE NEXT SCHOOL
SHOOTING WE'LL BE TALKING ABOUT
GUN CONTROL AGAIN.
I WOULD PUT MONEY ON IT THAT
BETWEEN NOW AND THAT NEXT
SHOOTING NO ONE'S GOING TO DO
ANYTHING.
I FEEL VERY COMFORTABLE SAYING
THAT.
NOTHING WILL BE DONE.
SO -- I JUST WOULD LIKE TO KNOW
WHAT TANGIBLE THINGS OUTSIDE OF
MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES WHICH I
THINK ARE A VERY, VERY IMPORTANT
ONE, BUT LET'S TABLE THAT AND
FOCUS ON GUN CONTROL.
WHAT HAS TO CHANGE SO THAT
PEOPLE CAN'T GET ACCESS TO SEMI
ON AUTOMATIC WEAPONS AND CAN GO
INTO A SCHOOL AND SHOOT UP A
BUNCH OF KIDS?
>> WELL, SOLEDAD, WITH ALL DUE
RESPECT, YOU KNOW, FIRST OF ALL,
WE DON'T EVEN KNOW THIS SHOOTER.
WE KNOW HIS NAME.
WE DON'T KNOW A WHOLE LOT MORE.
IT'S BEEN 24 HOURS SINCE THIS
TRAGEDY.
WE'RE MAKING A LOT OF
ASSUMPTIONS THAT WE SHOULDN'T
MAKE YET.
I WOULD VENTURE TO GUESS THIS IS
A VERY DEEPLY TROUBLED
INDIVIDUAL.
YES, I WILL HAVE THAT DEBATE
WITH YOU.
YOU KNOW, I HAVE AS I'VE SAID --
>> Reporter: WE KNOW THE WEAPONS
HE USED.
WE KNOW THE WEAPONS HE USED.
WE KNOW THAT HE HAD THREE
WEAPONS AT LEAST ON HIM.
SO YOU'RE RIGHT, THERE IS TONS
TO KNOW.
WE'RE WAITING FOR A PRESS
CONFERENCE BECAUSE THERE'S LOTS
MORE TO KNOW ABOUT THIS YOUNG
MAN WHO IS 20 YEARS OLD.
BUT WE TO DOO KN-- WE DO KNOW H
AND KILLED PEOPLE.
HE DIDN'T STAB THEM.
HE SHOT THEM.
THIS CONVERSATION AT SOME POINT
HAS TO GO TO WHAT IS THE NORMAL
AMOUNT OF GUNS THAT PEOPLE CAN
OWN AND HOW THEY'RE REGISTERED
AND TRACKED.
WE JUST -- ANOTHERWISE Y -- OTH
WE'LL HAVE THIS SAME
CONVERSATION AT THE SAME
TERRIBLE TRAGEDY.
I THINK YOU KNOW WE WILL, RIGHT?
>> I PRAY NOT.
OF COURSE, WE ALL PRAY THAT WE
-- NEVER AGAIN.
BUT SOLEDAD, YES, WE KNOW THAT
HE HAD THESE WEAPONS, BUT WE
HAVEN'T SEEN ANY TOXICOLOGY
RESULTS.
WE DON'T KNOW IF HE WAS USING,
WE DON'T KNOW IF HE WAS ADDICTED
TO PILLS.
WE HAVE NO IDEA IF HE'S BEEN
SEEKING MENTAL COUNSELING.
WE DON'T KNOW THOSE ANSWERS YET.
AND I THINK, YES, I WILL -- WE
CAN TALK ABOUT GUN CONTROL, YOU
AND I AS MOTHERS, AS REPUBLICAN
AND DEMOCRAT, AND WE SHOULD TALK
ABOUT MENTAL HEALTH AND WHO HE
WAS AND WHAT CONTRIBUTED.
AND YOU KNOW, THEN LET'S FO
FORMULATE THOSE OPINIONS.
I'M HAPPY TO HAVE THOSE
CONVERSATIONS BECAUSE I HAVE
LOOKED AT VARIOUS ISSUES ON GUN
CONTROL WHERE I'VE DIVERTED FROM
MY PARTY AGAIN.
IN THIS CASE, THIS GUY SERIOUSLY
SNAPPED.
AND THE GUNS DIDN'T MAKE HIM
SNAP.
HE SNAPPED AND THEN SOUGHT OUT
THE GUNS.
AND WHETHER THEY WERE HIS
MANAGER'S GUNS OR WHETHER THEY
-- HIS MOTHER'S GUNS OR WHETHER
THEY WERE SOMEBODY ELSE'S, HE
WAS GOING SNAP AND DO SOMETHING
HORRIFIC AND HEINOUS,
UNFORTUNATELY.
>> Reporter: WE KNOW -- BUT WE
KNOW HE USED GUNS, AND THAT'S
HOW HE KILLED 26 PEOPLE AND THEN
TOOK HIS MOTHER'S LIFE AND TOOK
HIS OWN LIFE.
IT WAS GUNS.
MARY BONO MACK, ALWAYS NICE TO
TALK TO YOU.
I'M GOING TO TAKE YOU OCCUPY
THAT.
YOU AND I WILL CONTINUE THIS
CONVERSATION.
I THINK PEOPLE ARE SICK OF ALL
THE -- YOU KNOW, THE
CONVERSATION AROUND IT.
AND WE NEVER ACTUALLY DO
ANYTHING.
AND I -- YOU KNOW, MAYBE IN
NATION PEOPLE OF TIRED OF THAT
AT THIS POINT.
I WOULD LIKE TO SEE THAT.
THANK YOU FOR TALKING WITH US.
>> THANK YOU, SOLEDAD.
I THINK WE SHOULD BE TALKING
ABOUT ALL OF THESE ISSUE.
THANK YOU.
>> Reporter: I APPRECIATED THAT.
MARY BONO MACK, CONGRESSWOMAN,
JOINING US THIS MORNING.
WE HAVE LOTS TO UPDATE YOU ON.
WE'VE BEEN WAITING FOR A PRESS
CONFERENCE.
IT WAS SUPPOSED TO HAPPEN AT
8:00.
IT'S BEEN DELAYED.
UNCLEAR WHY IT'S BEEN DELAYED.