>>> GOOD EVENING, EVERYONE, IT
IS 10:00 HERE IN NEWTOWN
CONNECTICUT, THE END OF A
HARROWING WEEK FOR THIS TOWN OR
ANY TOWN.
THERE ARE MANY DIFFICULT DAYS,
WEEKS AND MONTHS AHEAD.
STARTING TOMORROW, PARENTS WILL
BEGIN BURYING THEIR CHILDREN,
TRYING TO IMAGINE -- IT'S ALMOST
UNTHINKABLE.
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO FIND THE
WORDS.
ALL THE WORDS THAT WE CAN SAY IN
THIS HOUR ARE GOING TO SEEM SO
SMALL, THE FACE OF THE TRAGEDY
THAT HAS OCCURRED HERE.
NOW, IS A TIME TO LEAN ON ONE
ANOTHER OR THE PARENTS AND THE
LOVED ONES AND THE FAMILIES HERE
TO BE THE ONES TO LEAN ON.
THEY CAME TOGETHER FOR A
CONVINCE IL, CROWDING INTO THE
LOCAL HIGH SCHOOL JUST BEHIND
ME.
THE LOCAL HIGH SCHOOL AUDITORIUM
TO LISTEN TO SPIRITUAL LEADER
OFFERING ANY WORDS OF COMFORT
THEY COULD.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SPOKE AS WELL
AND SAID THAT WE AS A NATION ARE
SIMPLY NOT DOING ENOUGH TO KEEP
OUR CHILDREN SAFE.
HE PROMISED TO WORK, TO PUT AN
END TO FUTURE TRAGEDIES LIKE
THIS ONE.
WE'LL PLAY YOU HIS CALL FOR
ACTION SHORTLY.
BUT WE DON'T WANT TO FOCUS ON
THE KILLER.
FOR THE LAST SEVERAL DAYS WE
HAVEN'T SAID HIS NAME.
I DON'T WANT HISTORY TO REMEMBER
HIM.
WE AND THE PEOPLE HERE WANT YOU
TO REMEMBER THE TEACHERS AND
CHILDRENS AND THOSE WHOSE LIVES
HAVE BEEN SO UNFORTUNATELY
TAKEN.
PEOPLE WITH HOPES, DREAMS AND
STORIES.
EVEN THOUGH 20 OF THOSE STORIES
HAD JUST BEGUN.
WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THEIR
LIVES FROM PARENTS AND FRIENDS
AND LOCAL AND NATIONAL PAPERS
AND LOCAL BLOGS.
IF YOU REMEMBER AFTER THE
SHOOTING IN AURORA, THERE WAS A
VIGIL IN AURORA COLORADO.
EVERY TIME SOMEBODY'S NAME WAS
READ, THE CROWD SAID BACK, WE
WILL REMEMBER, WITH THAT IN MIND
TONIGHT, I THOUGHT WE'D JUST
TAKE A FEW MOMENTS TO REVIEW THE
NAMES OF EACH AND EVERY FALLEN
CHILD AND EVERY GROWN-UP AND
TELL YOU WHAT WE CAN ABOUT THEIR
LIVES.
CHARLOTTE BACON, 6 YEARS OLD.
WE WILL REMEMBER HER.
SHE WAS WEARING A NEW PINK DRESS
AND BOOTS, A HOLIDAY OUTFIT.
CHARLOTTE BEGGED HER MOM TO WEAR
IT TO SCHOOL THAT DAY.
HER BIG BROTHER WAS ALSO AT
SCHOOL THAT DAY, BUT WE'RE TOLD
HE MADE IT TO SAFETY.
HER UNCLE SAYS SHE COULD LIGHT
UP A ROOM.
WE'LL ALSO REMEMBER DANIEL
BARDEN, 7 YEARS OLD.
HE WAS A BUDDING ATHLETE.
HE SWAM, PLAYED SOCCER, WAS
MISSING TWO FRONT TEETH.
HIS FAMILY CALLED HIM FEARLESS.
WE WILL REMEMBER OLIVIA ENGEL AS
WELL, JUST SIX YEARS OLD, SHE
PLAYED TENNIS AND SOCCER.
WAS A BALLET DANCER AND A
PATIENT BIG SISTER TO HER
3-YEAR-OLD BROTHER.
SHE LOVED SCHOOL, COLORS PINK
AND PURPLE AND WAS GOING TO BE
AN ANGEL IN THE NATIVITY PLAY
SCHEDULED FOR JUST LAST NIGHT.
WE WILL REMEMBER 7-YEAR-OLD
JOSEPHINE GAY AS WELL.
SHE TURNED 7 ON TUESDAY.
SHE TOO LOVED THE COLOR PURPLE.
HER NEIGHBORS ARE HANGING PURPLE
BALLOONS FROM MAILBOXES AND
FENCES IN HER MEMORY.
WE WILL REMEMBER HER.
WE'LL ALSO REMEMBER ANA
MARQUEZ-GREENE, 6 YEARS OLD.
SHE GREW UP WITH MUSIC IN HER
EARS, HER DAD PLAYS JAZZ
SAXOPHONE AND FLUTE.
HE WROTE A SONG ABOUT HER
ENTITLED ANA GRACE.
WE'LL ALSO REMEMBER DYLAN
HOCKLEY, HE TOO WAS JUST 6 YEARS
OLD.
HE CAME FROM ENGLAND, MOVING
HERE TWO YEARS AGO.
HIS MOM RECENTLY CALLING THE
AREA A WONDERFUL PLACE TO LIVE
WITH INCREDIBLE NEIGHBORS AND
WONDERFUL SCHOOLS.
WE WILL REMEMBER DYLAN.
WE'LL ALSO REMEMBER 6-YEAR-OLD
MADELEINE HSU, A NEIGHBOR'S SON
WHO SHARED RIDES TO SCHOOL WITH
HER, REMEMBERS HER AS A KIND,
SWEET AND WONDERFUL GIRL.
WE'LL REMEMBER CATHERINE VIOLET
HUBBARD, ALSO JUST 6.
SHE LOVED ANIMALS.
INSTEAD OF FLOWERS, HER FAMILY
IS REQUESTING DONATIONS BE MADE
TO THE NEWTOWN ANIMAL SHELTER,
THAT'S PROBABLY WHAT SHE WOULD
HAVE WANTED.
WE WILL REMEMBER HER.
WE WILL REMEMBER 7-YEAR-OLD
CHASE KOWALSKI, FOR HIS LOVE OF
OUTDOOR SPORTS AND HIS TALENT
FOR THEM.
HE JUST WON HIS FIRST
MINI-TRIATHLON.
HE WAS ALWAYS OUTSIDE RIDING HIS
BIKE.
WE WILL REMEMBER CHASE.
WE WILL REMEMBER 6-YEAR-OLD
JESSE LEWIS WAS LEARNING HOW TO
RIDE A HORSE.
IT WAS ONLY NATURAL, HIS FAMILY
HAD FIVE OF THEM.
TWO MINIATURES, THREE DOGS, A
FLOCK OF CHICKENS.
HE LOVED TO TELL STORIES AND
LIVED LIFE BRAVE AND TRUE.
WE WILL REMEMBER.
WE'LL ALSO REMEMBER 6-YEAR-OLD
JAMES.
HE'S BEING REMEMBERED AS A
SWEETHEART OF A KID WITH SUCH AN
INNOCENT FACE.
A FACE THAT WE AND THEY AND
EVERYONE SHOULD REMEMBER.
WE'LL REMEMBER THE FACE OF
7-YEAR-OLD GRACE McDONNELL.
THE NEIGHBOR DESCRIBES IT AS THE
FACE OF AN ANGEL.
SHE WAS HER MOTHER'S LITTLE BEST
FRIEND.
HER FAMILY IN A BRIEF STATEMENT
SAYING, OUR DAUGHTER GRACE WAS
THE LOVE AND LIGHT OF OUR
FAMILY.
WORDS CANNOT ADEQUATELY EXPRESS
OUR SENSE OF LOSS.
WE TOO WILL REMEMBER GRACE.
AND WE'LL ALSO REMEMBER EMILIE
PARKER, JUST 6 YEARS OLD.
SHE WAS A MENTOR TO HER TWO
YOUNGER SISTERS AGES THREE AND
FOUR.
HER FATHER SAYS WHEN THEY NEEDED
COMFORT THEY LOOKED TO EMILIE.
THEY WILL REMEMBER HER AND SO
WILL WE.
WE WILL REMEMBER ANOTHER
6-YEAR-OLD, JACK PINTO
HE LOVED WRESTLING.
HE AND HIS TEAM WERE SCHEDULED
TO COMPETE THIS WEEKEND IN A
MATCH AGAINST THE NEW JERSEY
WRESTLING CLUB.
WE'LL REMEMBER HIM.
THERE'S SO MANY PEOPLE TO
REMEMBER, WE'LL REMEMBER NOAH
POZNER, 6 YEARS OLD, SMART AS A
WHIP ACCORDING TO HIS UNCLE.
HE LOVED READING AND FIGURING
THINGS OUT.
NOAH'S TWIN SISTER WAS AT SCHOOL
ON FRIDAY, THE TWO WERE SAID TO
BE INSEPARABLE.
SHE SURVIVED, HE DID NOT.
WE'LL REMEMBER 6-YEAR-OLD
CAROLINE FOR A TIME REFERRED TO
AS BOO BECAUSE SHE RESEMBLED THE
LITTLE GIRL FROM "MONSTERS INC."
WE WILL REMEMBER JESSICA REKOS.
SHE WANT EED COWGIRL BOOTS FOR
CHRISTMAS.
WE'LL REMEMBER AVIELLE RICHMAN.
SHE WAS EXCITED BECAUSE SHE WAS
ABOUT TO LOSE HER FIRST TOOTH.
BENJAMIN WHEELER'S BIRTH LED HIS
FAMILY HERE TO TOWN.
THEY MOVED OUT OF NEW YORK TO
SOME PLACE QUIET.
HE WAS ALSO 6 YEARS OLD.
WE'LL REMEMBER ALLISON WYATT,
ALSO 6 YEARS OLD.
NONE OF THE CHILDREN WERE OLDER
THAN 7.
WE'LL REMEMBER RACHEL DAVINO,
ANNE MARIE MURPHY.
WE WILL REMEMBER HER AND SO WILL
THIS COMMUNITY.
WE'LL REMEMBER 30-YEAR-OLD
LAUREN RUSSEAU WHO WANTED TO BE
A TEACHER BEFORE SHE EVEN
STARTED KINDERGARTEN.
SHE WAS A FULL TIME SUBSTITUTE
AT SANDY HOOK.
WE'LL REMEMBER MARY SHERLACH,
THE PROUD MOTHER OF TWO YOUNG
DAUGHTERS.
WE WILL REMEMBER VICTORIA SOTO.
NO ONE IN THIS TOWN WILL EVER
FORGET VICTORIA SOTO, SHE DIED
TRYING TO PROTECT THE LIVES OF
HER FIRST GRADERS.
SHE WAS THE OLDEST OF FOUR
CHILDREN.
AND, OF COURSE, THE SCHOOL
PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG.
EVEN LITTLE KIDS KNOW WHEN
SOMEONE CARES ABOUT THEM, AND
THAT WAS HER.
WE WILL REMEMBER HER AS WE
REMEMBER ALL 26 LIVES LOST IN
THAT SCHOOL THAT DAY.
26 LIVES CUT SHORT FRIDAY
MORNING AT SANDY CREEK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
NEWTOWN IS NOW THE NATION'S
HEARTACHE.
IT IS OUR OPEN WOUND.
A WHOLE SO LARGE THAT WE'RE NOT
SURE GOD CAN FILL IT.
SOMETHING TO HOPE FOR.
HIS HOPE IS, EVERYONE'S HOPE, AS
WEZ BRING YOU SOME MOMENTS FROM
TONIGHT'S VIGIL, STARTING WITH
FIRST RESPONDERS COMING INTO THE
AUDITORIUM TO A ROUND OF
APPLAU
APPLAUSE.
[ APPLAUSE ]
♪
>> WE GATHER HERE IN MEMORY OF
20 BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN AND 6
REMARKABLE ADULTS.
THEY LOST THEIR LIVES IN A
SCHOOL.
IT COULD HAVE BEEN ANY SCHOOL.
IN A QUIET TOWN FULL OF GOOD AND
DECENT PEOPLE.
THAT COULD BE ANY TOWN IN
AMERICA.
HERE IN NEWTOWN, I COME TO OFFER
THE LOVE AND PRAYERS OF A
NATION.
I AM VERY MINDFUL THAT MERE
WORDS CANNOT MATCH THE DEPTHS OF
YOUR SORROW.
NOR CAN THEY HEAL YOUR WOUNDED
HEARTS.
I CAN ONLY HOPE IT HELPS FOR YOU
TO KNOW THAT YOU'RE NOT ALONE IN
YOUR GRIEF THAT OUR WORLD TOO
HAS BEEN TORN APART.
THAT ALL ACROSS THIS LAND OF
OURS, WE HAVE WEPT WITH YOU.
WE'VE PULLED OUR CHILDREN TIGHT.
AND YOU MUST KNOW THAT WHATEVER
MEASURE OF COMFORT WE CAN
PROVIDE, WE WILL PROVIDE.
>> WITH ME NOW ARE TWO CLERGY
MEMBERS WHO SPOKE AT THE VIGIL.
SENIOR MINISTER OF THE NEWTOWN
CONGREGATIONAL CHURCH.
WHAT DO YOU WANT TO COME OUT OF
THIS?
WHAT DO YOU WANT PEOPLE TO KNOW?
>> I'M HOPING, ANDERSON, THIS
WILL BE THE TIPPING POINT IN OUR
COUNTRY.
I FEEL THAT CHILDREN ARE
INUNDATED WITH THE CULTURE OF
VIOLENCE FROM A VERY YOUNG AGE.
FROM THE TOYS THAT WE PLAY WITH
TO THE MOVIES THAT WE SEE AND
THE TV THAT WE SEE.
THAT WE CAN DO BETTER, AND WE
CAN MAKE GAMES THAT ARE EXCITING
THAT HAVE A POSITIVE OBJECTIVE.
AND WE REALLY NEED TO DO THAT,
BECAUSE I THINK IT'S TOO
COMMONPLACE, THE VIOLENT
REACTION.
OF COURSE, THE INDIVIDUAL IS
DERANGED BUT THERE'S A PART OF
ME THAT THINKS IF WE HAD MORE OF
A CULTURE OF PEACE THAT THESE
KIND OF EVENTS WOULD BE LESS
LIKELY TO HAPPEN.
>> WHAT ARE YOU HOPING COMES OUT
OF THIS?
>> WELL, I'M HOPING FOR OUR
COMMUNITY THAT THE COMMUNITY
GROWS EVEN CLOSER AND STRONGER.
I KNOW PEOPLE HAVE SPOKEN ABOUT
HOW CLOSE AND STRONG IT WAS
BEFORE.
BUT AS YOU KNOW, A TRAGEDY LIKE
THIS, WE'RE VERY VULNERABLE.
BUT I ALSO HAVE HOPE THAT WE CAN
BECOME STRONGER AND CLOSER AND
CARE FOR ONE ANOTHER IN DEEPER
WAYS.
>> IT'S EXTRAORDINARY JUST THE
LAST COUPLE DAYS, I'VE BEEN
HERE.
COMPLETE STRANGERS COME UP TO
ONE ANOTHER ON THE STREET AND
ARE HUGGING AND SHARING, SHARING
THEIR HEARTS WITH EACH OTHER.
>> THERE'S AN OUTPOURING.
NOT ONLY IN THE TOWN, BUT FOR
PEOPLE AROUND THE WORLD.
AND -- BUT THAT WILL SLOWLY
DISSIPATE.
AND THE ATTENTION WILL DISAPPEAR
FROM THIS PLACE, AND WE'LL BE
RETURNING TO LIVES THAT ARE
SUPPOSED TO BE NORMAL.
FOR MANY PEOPLE, THEY WON'T FEEL
NORMAL AGAIN.
HOW DO WE MAKE THOSE LIVES FEEL
CONNECTED AND CLOSER AND CARED
FOR, AND VIBRANT?
BECAUSE WE DON'T WANT THIS EVENT
TO ZEE FINE THE SPIRIT OF OUR
FAITH COMMUNITIES, THE SPIRIT OF
THIS COMMUNITY.
WE WANT PEOPLE TO KNOW THAT
THERE IS SOMETHING MORE,
SOMETHING HOPEFUL, SOMETHING
THAT WE CAN EVEN BECOME MORE
COMPASSIONATE, MORE CARING, SOME
OF THE THINGS THAT WE JUST
TALKED ABOUT, HOW WE SEE PEOPLE
NOT JUST HERE IN TOWN, BUT IN
THE WORLD.
>> I'VE SEEN REPRESENTATIVES AND
REMEMBERS ON THE STAGE.
IT WAS A POWERFUL MOVING
STATEMENT.
WHAT DO YOU -- HOW -- THERE'S SO
MANY PARENTS AROUND THE WORLD
WHO ARE FOLLOWING THIS, WHO
DON'T KNOW WHAT TO SAY TO THEIR
CHILDREN, DON'T KNOW HOW TO
EXPLAIN IT.
HOW DO YOU COUNCIL SOMEBODY.
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THEM?
>> YOU MEAN, AROUND THE COUNTRY?
>> YEAH, OR HERE, ANYWHERE.
>> WE HAVE YOUNG ONES TOO, WE
HAVE FIRST GRADERS, WE WANT THEM
TO KNOW THAT SOMETHING BAD
HAPPENED.
WE HAVE TO TELL THEM SOMETHING.
WE HAVEN'T SAID ANYTHING YET.
IT'S VERY UNUSUAL AND THE BAD
MAN CAN'T HURT ANYBODY ANY MORE.
THAT'S HOW WE WOULD, AS FIRST
GRADERS WE WOULD APPROACH THAT.
AND WE JUST NEED TO WORK TO MAKE
OUR COMMUNITY BETTER, AND NOT TO
BE AFRAID.
YOU'RE SAFE.
>> NO DOUBT YOU'VE HAD TO
COUNCIL PEOPLE WHO HAVE LOST
LOVED ONES, WHAT DO YOU SAY IN
THAT -- IS THERE ANYTHING TO
SAY?
>> THERE ARE THINGS TO SAY, BUT
I THINK OFTEN TIMES WE'RE
INCLINED TO WANT TO SAY THINGS
FIRST.
I THINK LISTENING IS THE FIRST
RESPONSE, IS TO LISTEN TO
PEOPLE'S GRIEF, LISTEN TO WHAT
THEY'RE -- EVEN IF THEY CAN'T
ARTICULATE NOT COMING IN
THINKING THAT A CERTAIN WORD,
PHRASE OR EVEN PEOPLE OF FAITH,
CERTAIN SCRIPTURES WILL JUST
SOLVE OR HEAL INSTANTLY.
BUT THOSE WORDS OF SCRIPTURE,
THOSE WORDS ARE SIGNIFICANT.
BUT REALIZING THAT WE HAVE TO
CONTINUE TO LISTEN AND TO FIND
APPROPRIATE WAYS WITH THEM TO
FIND EXPRESSION AND A MEANING
THAT COME OUT OF OUR TRADITIONS.
FOLKS I COUNCIL IN MY OWN
TRADITION.
THAT WOULD BE WHAT I DROP ON.
>> THE LOSS OF A CHILD IS
SOMETHING -- THAT PAIN NEVER
GOES AWAY.
>> IT'S REALLY HORRIBLE.
AND WHEN YOU SEE THE PARENTS
WAILING LIKE THAT, YOU REALIZE,
THAT'S HOW WE WOULD BE IF WE
WERE THERE TOO.
THESE ARE ALL OF OUR CHILDREN.
AND SO -- I THINK MATT SAID IT
VERY WELL, YOU TAKE YOUR CUES,
SOME PEOPLE WILL LIKE A
THEOLOGICAL EXPLANATION.
NOAH'S MOTHER, I TOLD HER THIS
MORNING, WHERE IS THE 6-YEAR-OLD
INSIDE OF YOU READY TO GO?
AND SHE SAID, WELL, IT'S STILL
IN ME.
IN A SENSE,HERE'S A SPIRITUAL
IDEA THAT THERE IS NO DOUBT,
THERE'S A TRANSFORMATION, AS WE,
THROUGH NATION GROW OUR
6-YEAR-OLD IS STILL SURROUNDED
BY THE GREATER ASPECT OF
OURSELVES AS WE GROW AND MATURE.
AND SO IT'S A LEAP OF FAITH TO
SAY AFTER WE LEAVE OUR BODY THAT
WE BECOME PART OF A GREATER
MATRIX OR A GREATER MOTIF IN THE
UNIVERSE.
>> I APPRECIATE BOTH OF YOU FOR
BEING WITH US TONIGHT, BUT ALSO
JUST BEING ON THE STAGE AND WHAT
YOU SAID, I THOUGHT IT WAS
EXTRAORDINARILY POWERFUL.
>> THANK YOU.
>> WISH YOU THE BEST.
>>> WHEN WE COME BACK,
REMEMBERING PRINCIPAL DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG.
I'M WITH HER HUSBAND AND
CHILDREN.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
THIS FAMILY USED
Capital One Venture Miles
TO COME HOME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE...
SADLY, THEIR BROTHER'S
WHITE CHRISTMAS
JUST GOT "BLACKED OUT."
[ Brother ]
BUT IT'S THE FAMILY PARTY!
REALLY JINGLES YOUR BELLS,
DOESN'T IT?
MY GIFT TO YOU!
THE Capital One Venture Card!
FOR ANY FLIGHT, ANY TIME!
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE!
HOW ILLUMINATING.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
LET ME GUESS, AM I
ON THE NAUGHTY LIST AGAIN?
HO HO HO!
>>> THE PRINCIPAL WHO -- GOD
BLESS HER LOST HER LIFE.
SHE WAS A VERY SPECIAL PERSON.
AND YOU WILL THE PARENTS KNEW
THAT.
>> THE PRINCIPAL OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY WAS RESPECTED AND
ADMIRED BY THE TEACHERS AND
PARENTS AND LOVED BY THE
STUDENTS AS WELL.
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG WAS HER NAME,
SHE BECAME PRINCIPAL TWO YEARS
AGO, SHE WAS A MOM OF ONE OF THE
FIRST GRADERS, SHE NEVER SAW HER
WITHOUT A SMILE, ON THAT AWFUL
DAY AT THAT SCHOOL WHO SURVIVED,
SAY DAWN DIED PROTECTING THEM,
CONFRONTING THE GUNMAN HERSELF.
IT WAS A TERRIBLE LOSS OF A
BELOVED PRINCIPAL, MORE
IMPORTANTLY, OF A WIFE, MOTHER
AND GRANDMOTHER.
TONIGHT HER DAUGHTER POSTED THIS
PICTURE ON TWITTER OF PRESIDENT
OBAMA HOLDING DAWN HOCHSPRUNG'S
GRANDDAUGHTER.
MY MOM WOULD BE SO PROUD TO SEE
PRESIDENT OBAMA HOLDING HER
DAUGHTER.
BUT NOT AS PROUD AS I AM ABOUT
HER.
GARY TUCHMAN SPOKE TO THE FAMILY
ABOUT WHAT A WONDERFUL WOMAN SHE
WAS.
>> Reporter: SHE WAS QUITE A BIT
YOUNGER THAN HER HUSBAND GEORGE,
WHEN THEY GOT MARRIED TEN YEARS
AGO, GEORGE WAS MARRYING HIS
BOSS.
>> SHE WAS AN ASSISTANT
PRINCIPAL AT OUR SCHOOL, AND I
WAS A 7th GRADE MATH TEACHER AT
THAT TIME.
AND I JUST FELL IN LOVE WITH
HER.
>> GEORGE MADE THE BIG DECISION,
THE TIME HAD COME TO PROPOSE.
>> SHE TURNED ME DOWN FIVE
TIMES.
>> YOU ASKED HER TO MARRY YOU,
BUT SHE TURNED YOU DOWN?
>> FIVE TIMES.
>> WHAT ABOUT THE SIXTH TIME?
>> THE SIXTH TIME I WAITED UNTIL
IT WAS NOT SUCH ROUGH SAILING.
WE GOT MARRIED ON THE SWOOP OUT
OF MYSTIC.
BETH, AMY AND ANN ARE GEORGE'S
DAUGHTERS FROM HIS FIRST
MARRIAGE.
ERICA IS DAWN'S DAUGHTER FROM
HER FIRST MARRIAGE.
HER OTHER DAUGHTER WAS OUT WHILE
WE WERE AT THE HOUSE.
THEY'RE A BLENDED BUT VERY CLOSE
FAMILY WITH 11 GRANDCHILDREN.
>> WE BUILT THIS BEAUTIFUL HOUSE
IN THE ADIRONDACKS, THE DREAM
WAS -- IT WAS GOING TO BE DAWN'S
HOUSE, BECAUSE I WAS GOING TO
DIE.
I'M MUCH OLDER THAN DAWN.
IT WAS GOING TO BE HER HOUSE AND
THE CHILDREN AND GRANDCHILDREN
COULD USE THE HOUSE ON THE LAKE.
THERE WOULD BE ROOMS DOWN STAIRS
FOR KIDS.
IT WAS GOING TO BE DAWN'S HOUSE
ULTIMATELY WITH ALL THE
CHILDREN.
ALL THE CHILDREN.
AND NOW IT'S ME.
I CAN'T -- I DON'T THINK I CAN
DO THAT.
>> I WANT TO REITERATE TO YOU,
GEORGE, HAVE YOU THESE BEAUTIFUL
DAUGHTERS AND SON IN LAWS AND
GRANDCHILDREN, AND EVERYONE WILL
BE HERE TO TAKE CARE OF YOU, IS
THAT RIGHT, LADIES?
>> MY JOB HAS ALWAYS BEEN TO
TAKE CARE OF OTHER PEOPLE?
>> IT'S ALL RIGHT IF SOME PEOPLE
TAKE CARE OF YOU FOR A WHILE?
>> NO ONE TAKES CARE OF ME.
>> STOP BEING SO STUBBORN.
>> IN THE MIDDLE OF THE DAY
FRIDAY, THIS IS HOW GEORGE FOUND
OUT WHAT HAPPENED.
>> ONE OF THE KIDS CAME UP WITH
A COMPUTER AND SAID, SOMETHING'S
HAPPENING AT SANDY HOOK SCHOOL
AND YOUR WIFE'S BEEN KILLED.
>> GEORGE RACED OUT OF SCHOOL
AND INTO A NIGHTMARE, LIKE ALL
THE FAMILIES OF VICTIMS THEYEN
WATT TO KNOW MORE.
AND ON THIS DAY THEY HAVE
LEARNED MORE.
TWO TEACHERS WHO SURVIVED SAID
THEY WERE HAVING A MEETING WITH
DAWN WHEN THE SHOTS RANG OUT.
>> SHE PUT HERSELF IN JEOPARDY,
AND I HAVE BEEN ANGRY ABOUT THAT
UNTIL THE TWO WOMEN I MET TODAY,
SHE TOLD THEM TO RUN TO SHELTER
WHEN SHE CONFRONTED THE GUNMAN.
SHE COULD HAVE AVOIDED THAT.
SHE COULDN'T, I KNEW SHE
WOULDN'T.
I'M NOT ANGRY ANY MORE.
I'M NOT ANGRY, I'M JUST VERY
SAD.
THEY SAID, WE WERE AT THE
MEETING, THERE WERE GUNSHOTS.
SOMEBODY SHOT THE WINDOW,
SOMEBODY CAME IN, INTO THE --
NOT INTO THE OFFICE, BUT INTO
THE BUILDING, THE FOYER OF THE
BUILDING.
DAWN TOLD US TO GO HIDE, AND SHE
AND AT LEAST ONE OTHER TEACHER
RAN OUT AND ACTUALLY TRIED TO
SUBDUE THE KILLER.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE THAT COMES
FROM, DAWN WAS ALL OF 5'2".
>> EVERYONE HERE IS PROUD, NO
ONE MORE SO THAN ERICA, WHO SAID
HER MOM WAS ALWAYS THERE FOR HER
DAUGHTERS.
>> EVERY GAME, PRACTICE, SHE WAS
THERE.
DANCE COMPETITION, SHE WAS DOING
HOMEWORK ON THE BLEACHERS, BUT
SHE WAS THERE.
AND SHE WAS MY ROCK, MY ROCK.
>> AND NOW SHE IS A HERO TOO.
>> THE FINAL THING I WANT TO ASK
YOU IS, WHAT WOULD YOU SAY TO
YOUR MOM RIGHT NOW?
>> COME BACK.
JUST COME BACK.
>> GARY TUCHMAN JOINS ME NOW
LIVE.
I GUESS SOME PEOPLE DON'T
UNDERSTAND WHY PEOPLE WOULD TALK
AT A TIME LIKE THIS.
WHAT I FOUND IS OFTEN TIMES
PEOPLE WANT YOU TO KNOW ABOUT
THEIR LOVED ONE.
WANT YOU TO KNOW ABOUT THE LIFE
THEY LIVED, NOT JUST HOW THEIR
LIFE ENDED.
>> THAT'S RIGHT, ANDERSON.
AND THEY ARE SUCH A WONDERFUL
AND AMAZING FAMILY.
WE'RE SO GRATEFUL THEY LET US
INTO THEIR HOME ON ADAY LIKE
THIS.
IT'S VERY IMPORTANT FOR THEM TO
STAY CLOSE AND STAY UNITED.
THAT'S WHAT WILL GIVE THEM
STRENGTH.
OF THE FIVE DAUGHTERS, TWO OF
THEM LIVE IN CONNECTICUT.
ONE LIVES IN PENNSYLVANIA, ONE
IN NEW HAMPSHIRE, ONE LIVES IN
LONDON, THEY PLAN TO STAY
TOGETHER FOR A LONG TIME TO GIVE
THEIR FATHER GEORGE STRENGTH.
THEY HAVE A HAPPY EVENT COMING
UP IN JULY.
SHE'S GETTING MARRIED IN JULY.
THEY ALL BELIEVE THAT THEIR
MOTHER'S SPIRIT WILL BE THERE
WITH THEM AT THE WEDDING
CEREMONY IN JULY.
ANDERSON?
>> APPRECIATE THE REPORTING,
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
A KINDERGARTEN TEACHER AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
SHE JOINS ME LIVE.
I SPOKE TO YOU ON THE PHONE
FRIDAY.
I'VE BEEN THINKING ABOUT YOU ALL
WEEKEND.
I THINK HEROES ARE TEACHERS
EVERY DAY AROUND THE COUNTRY.
I FIND -- I JUST THINK WHAT YOU
DID WAS SO HEROIC.
YOU -- EXPLAIN AGAIN, YOU
HEARD -- YOU KNEW SOMETHING WAS
GOING WRONG.
HOW?
>> WELL, I MEAN WE WERE IN OUR
CLASSROOM, WE HEARD WHAT SOUNDED
LIKE GUNSHOTS, NOISES.
>> YOU HEARD THAT --
>> WELL, THERE WAS A LOUD
SPEAKER, THE PA SYSTEM WAS NOT
WORKING IN THE WAY IT NORMALLY
IS, YOU DON'T USUALLY HEAR
THINGS UNLESS SOMEONE MAKES AN
ANNOUNCEMENT.
THERE WERE NOISES THAT DIDN'T
SOUND CORRECT.
THERE WAS NO ONE TELLING US IT
WAS A DRILL.
WE TOOK THE CHILDREN AND WENT
INTO A LOCKDOWN, WE GO TO A
CERTAIN PLACE IN THE ROOM.
WE PULL THE BLINDS DOWN, WE LOCK
THE CLASSROOM DOORS AND WE COVER
THE WINDOW AT THE DOOR.
>> THIS IS SOMETHING YOU HAD
PRACTICED.
>> ABOUT A MONTH OR SO BEFORE,
DAWN MAKES SURE WE DO THAT.
AND WE GO TO A SAFE PLACE AND
TYPICALLY WHEN IT'S A DRILL THEY
TELL US, OKAY, AND WE EVEN EXIT
THE BUILDING FOLLOWING A CERTAIN
PATH.
IF THERE WAS AN EMERGENCY WE
WOULD GO DOWN TO THE SANDY HOOK
FIREHOUSE AND GATHER THERE,
WHICH IS WHAT WE DID THAT DAY.
WE KNEW THAT --
>> BUT YOU SAT THE KIDS DOWN.
>> WE SAT IN THE CUBBY AREA,
AWAY FROM THE DOOR SO NO ONE
COULD SEE US, READ THEM A STORY,
TALKED TO THEM.
THEY KEPT SAYING HOW COME WE'RE
HERE FOR SO LONG.
WELL, IT WILL BE A LITTLE
LONGER.
WHEN THEY'RE FIVE YOU DO
WHATEVER YOU CAN TO KEEP THEM
SAFE AND CALM.
>> THE COURAGE FOR YOU TO BE
ABLE TO JUST SIT THERE AND READ
A STORY AND KEEP THEM CALM.
>> I THINK THE ADRENALINE KICKS
IN AND YOU DO WHAT YOU HAVE TO
DO.
THERE WERE TWO OTHER PEOPLE IN
THE ROOM THAT WERE HELPING ME
WITH PULLING DOWN THE BLINDS AND
THAT, I WAS FOCUSED ON THE KIDS.
AND JUST KEEPING THEM SAFE.
I'M NOT ABOUT TO TELL THEM THAT
I THINK SOMETHING IS VERY BAD OR
VERY WRONG.
WE WAITED AND WAITED.
IT SEEMED LIKE A VERY LONG TIME.
MAYBE IT WAS 20 MINUTES A HALF
HOUR, I'M NOT SURE.
THERE WERE KNOCKS AT THE DOOR.
IT WAS POLICE, SOMEONE TELLING
US THAT WE HAD TO LEAVE.
DIDN'T WANT TO OPEN THE DOOR AT
FIRST, BUT WE DID.
THEY SAID, HAVE THE CHILDREN
WALK HOLD HANDS, COVER THEIR
EYES IF THEY COULD -- HE DIDN'T
SAY WHY, HE JUST SAID HAVE THEM
DO IT.
AT 5 IT'S NOT SO EASY TO CLOSE
YOUR EYES AND WALK.
SO I HAD THEM LOOK TOWARD THE
WALL.
I SAID, REMEMBER THE ADVENTURE
WE HAD.
WE'RE GOING TO DO THAT AGAIN.
>> HOW ARE YOU HOLDING UP?
>> AGAIN, ADRENALINE.
YOU ARE MOVING, YOU KNOW YOU
HAVE TO GET TO SAFETY.
I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT THE SITUATION
WAS OCCURRING, WE DIDN'T HAVE
ANY INFORMATION.
>> HOW ARE YOU HOLDING UP NOW?
>> HOW AM I HOLDING UP NOW?
>> YOU KNEW SOME OF THE KIDS?
>> TEN OF THEM.
TEN OF THEM WERE IN MY CLASS
LAST YEAR.
I WANT TO ATTEND SOME OF THE
SERVICES, I'M SURE SOME FAMILIES
WANT PRIVACY.
THERE'S A FEW CHILDREN WHO I'VE
HAD NOT JUST THEM, I'VE HAD
THEIR SIBLINGS AND IN ONE CASE,
I'VE HAD ALL THREE.
SO OUR FAMILIES WERE CLOSE -- AT
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL WE'RE A TIGHT
KNIT GROUP AND WE KNOW -- AND I
LIVE IN THE COMMUNITY ALSO,
SO --
>> AND DAWN AND ALL THE OTHERS.
OBVIOUSLY -- WHAT DO YOU WANT
PEOPLE TO KNOW ABOUT THEM, ABOUT
THIS KMOONT.
>> I WANT THEM TO BE ABLE TO
COME BACK TO SCHOOL.
I DON'T KNOW IF WE'LL COME BACK
TO SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
I HEAR WE'RE GOING TO BE
POSSIBLY MOVED TO ANOTHER
BUILDING SOMEWHERE ELSE.
WE NEED TO GET THE KIDS BACK IN
SCHOOL.
WE NEED TO SEE THEM.
IT WAS HELPFUL TONIGHT TO SEE
SOME OF THE FAMILIES AND GIVE
THEM A HUG.
THEY'RE CALLING US ALL HEROES.
WE DON'T FEEL LIKE THAT.
I WAS ABLE TO TELL EVERYBODY IN
MY CLASS, YOUR KIDS ARE SAFE.
THAT MADE ME FEEL GOOD.
>> YOU'RE A HERO TO ME AND I
THINK TO A LOT OF PEOPLE.
I APPRECIATE YOU TALKING TO ME.
>> THANK YOU.
OKAY.
>> AMAZING.
COMING UP, WE WANT TO PLAY YOU
MORE OF PRESIDENT OBAMA'S SPEECH
AT THE MEMORIAL SERVICE TONIGHT.
AT ONE POINT THE PRESIDENT
ASKING IF WE CAN HONESTLY SAY
WE'RE DOING ENOUGH TO KEEP OUR
CHILDREN SAFE FROM HARM.
>> WE SAY WE'RE TRULY DOING
ENOUGH TO GIVE ALL THE CHILDREN
OF THIS COUNTRY THE CHANCE THEY
DESERVE TO LIVE OUT THEIR LIVES
IN HAPPINESS AND WITH PURPOSE.
I'VE BEEN REFLECTING ON THIS THE
LAST FEW DAYS.
IF WE'RE HONEST WITH OURSELVES,
THE ANSWER IS NO.
WE'RE NOT DOING ENOUGH.
STAND.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
>>> WE WANT TO SHARE A VIDEO
WITH YOU.
IT'S VIDEO ALL PARENTS TAKE OF
THEIR CHILDREN.
A VIDEO CHRONICLING THE SWEET
MOMENTS, THE SMALL MOMENTS
MAKING UP CHILDHOOD.
IT'S A VIDEO OF A CHILD WHO DIED
IN THIS TRAGEDY.
HER NAME ANA MARQUEZ-GREENE.
HER BROTHER ISIAH WAS ALSO AT
THE SCHOOL, HE WAS NOT HARMED.
ANA'S FATHER GAVE US PERMISSION
TO SHOW THIS VIDEO.
OTHERWISE WE WOULDN'T SHOW IT.
THEY WANT YOU TO SEE HER AS SHE
WAS, SINGING AND PRAISING GOD.
TONIGHT WE REMEMBER ANA, WE
REMEMBER ALL THE CHILDREN.
>> COME NOW ALL MIGHTY KING.
♪
COME NOW ALL MIGHTY KING ♪
>> IT'S BEEN AN INCREDIBLY
EMOTIONAL NIGHT HERE IN NEWTOWN
CONNECTICUT, AS IT HAS BEEN THE
LAST SEVERAL NIGHTS AS THE
COMMUNITY CAME TOGETHER.
PRESIDENT OBAMA MET WITH
VICTIM'S FAMILIES AND SPOKE AT
THE SERVICE.
WE WANT TO PLAY YOU MORE OF WHAT
HE SAID TONIGHT WITH SINCERE
HOPE THAT HIS WORDS CAME AS SOME
SMALL MEASURE OF COMFORT
TONIGHT.
>> THIS IS OUR FIRST TASK,
CARING FOR OUR CHILDREN.
IT'S OUR FIRST JOB.
IF WE DON'T GET THAT RIGHT, WE
DON'T GET ANYTHING RIGHT.
THAT'S HOW, AS A SOCIETY, WE
WILL BE JUDGED.
AND BY THAT MEASURE, CAN WE
TRULY SAY AS A NATION THAT WE'RE
MEETING OUR OBLIGATIONS?
CAN WE HONESTLY SAY THAT WE'RE
DOING ENOUGH TO KEEP OUR
CHILDREN, ALL OF THEM SAFE FROM
HARM?
>> I'VE BEEN REFLECTING ON THIS
THE LAST FEW DAYS, IF WE'RE
HONEST WITH OURSELVES, THE
ANSWER IS NO.
WE'RE NOT DOING ENOUGH.
AND WE WILL HAVE TO CHANGE.
SINCE I'VE BEEN PRESIDENT, THIS
IS THE FOURTH TIME WE HAVE COME
TOGETHER TO COMFORT A GRIEVING
COMMUNITY TORN APART BY MASS
SHOOTINGS.
FOURTH TIME WE'VE HUGGED
SURVIVORS.
FOURTH TIME WE'VE CONSOLED THE
FAMILIES OF VICTIMS.
AND IN BETWEEN THERE HAVE BEEN A
SERIES OF SHOOTINGS, DAILY
REPORTS OF VICTIMS, MANY OF THEM
CHILDREN, IN SMALL TOWNS AND BIG
CITIES ALL ACROSS AMERICA.
VICTIMS WHOSE MUCH OF THE TIME
THEY'RE ONLY FAULT WAS BEING IN
THE WRONG PLACE AT THE WRONG
TIME.
WE CAN'T TOLERATE THIS ANY MORE.
THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
AND TO END THEM WE MUST CHANGE.
WE WILL BE TOLD THAT THE CAUSES
OF SUCH VIOLENCE ARE COMPLEX AND
THAT IS TRUE.
NO SINGLE LAW, NO SET OF LAWS
CAN ELIMINATE EVIL FROM THE
WORLD OR PREVENT EVERY SENSELESS
ACT OF VIOLENCE IN OUR SOCIETY.
BUT THAT CAN'T BE AN EXCUSE FOR
INACTION.
SURELY WE CAN DO BETTER THAN
THIS.
IF THERE'S EVEN ONE STEP WE CAN
TAKE TO SAVE ANOTHER CHILD OR
ANOTHER PARENT OR ANOTHER TOWN
FROM THE GRIEF THAT'S VISITED
TUCSON AND AURORA AND EAU CREEK
AND NEWTOWN AND COMMUNITIES
BEFORE THAT, THEN SURELY WE HAVE
AN OBLIGATION TO TRY.
IN THE COMING WEEKS I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT TO MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS TO PARENTS
AND EDUCATORS IN AN EFFORT AIMED
AT PREVENTING MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS.
BECAUSE WHAT CHOICE DO WE HAVE.
WE CAN'T ACCEPT EVENTSES LIKE
THIS AS RIOUTINE.
ARE WE REALLY PREPARED TO SAY
THAT WE'RE POWERLESS IN THE FACE
OF SUCH CARNAGE?
THAT THE POLITICS ARE TOO HARD?
ARE WE PREPARED TO SAY THAT SUCH
VIOLENCE VISITED ON OUR CHILDREN
YEAR AFTER YEAR AFTER YEAR IS
SOMEHOW THE PRICE OF OUR
FREEDOM?
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA EARLIER
TONIGHT SPEAKING TO HIGH SCHOOL
JUST BEHIND US.
WOLF BLITZER NOW JOINS ME LIVE.
I WAS WONDERING ABOUT YOUR
THOUGHTS WHILE LISTENING TO THE
PRESIDENT.
>> HE DID TONIGHT WHAT HE DIDN'T
DO THE EARLIER TIMES, HE TRIED
TO COMFORT THE NATION.
HE SPECIFICALLY PROMISED THAT HE
WAS GOING TO TAKE STEPS.
HE DIDN'T GO INTO DETAILS, TAKE
STEPS TO TRY TO MAKE SURE THAT
THESE SENSELESS KILLINGS DON'T
HAPPEN AGAIN, EVEN IF YOU CAN
SAVE A FEW LIVES.
OBVIOUSLY WHAT HE'S REFERRING TO
IS LEGISLATION DEALING WITH GUN
CONTROL.
>> AND ALSO MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES.
>> I THINK THERE'S A LOT OF
THINGS YOU CAN POTENTIALLY DO.
THERE WILL BE A POLITICAL FIGHT.
OBVIOUSLY THE HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES IN THE SENATE,
THERE ARE NO GUARANTEES.
HE DID MAKE THAT COMMITMENT, HE
PROMISED HE WAS GOING TO DO, AND
I THINK MAYOR BLOOMBERG OF NEW
YORK WANTS HIM TO DO, NOT JUST
TALK A LITTLE BIT, BUT START
TAKING ACTION.
>> IT'S SOMETHING HE HAD TALKED
ABOUT BEFORE BECOMING PRESIDENT.
>> HE DIDN'T JUST HAVE PROBLEMS
WITH REPUBLICANS WHO ARE OPPOSED
TO STRICTER GUN CONTROL.
THERE ARE PLENTY OF DEMOCRATS
OUT THERE, THEY THINK IT'S SUCH
A LOSING ISSUE.
HE HAS A LOT OF OTHER ISSUES, HE
HAS A FISCAL CLIFF.
I THINK HE'S GOING TO DEAL WITH
THIS -- YOU KNOW, HE'S IN HIS
SECOND TERM, HE DOESN'T THE HAVE
TO WORRY ABOUT GETTING
RE-ELECTED.
I DON'T KNOW IF HE'LL SUCCEED.
I'VE BEEN IN WASHINGTON A LONG
TIME, GUN CONTROL IS AN ISSUE.
I THINK HE'S GOING TO TRY.
>> A CRIME LIKE THIS HAS SHOCKED
THE NATION.
WHETHER IT LEADS TO CHANGE,
WE'LL HAVE TO SEE.
ON THE MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES.
YOU AND SANJAY WERE TALKING
ABOUT THIS EARLIER, MENTAL
HEALTH IS ODDLY DEALT WITH IN
THIS COUNTRY.
IT'S NOT DEALT WITH OR
CONSIDERED IN THE SAME WAY AS A
DISEASE LIKE CANCER.
>> TIPPER GORE, REMEMBER TIPPER
GORE, SHE DEALT WITH THIS ISSUE,
AND TRIED TO BRING IT TO THE
FOREFRONT BUT IT'S SORT OF GONE
AWAY.
GUN CONTROL IS IMPORTANT, BUT
MENTAL HEALTH, DEALING WITH
THIS, AND TAKING IT OUT OF THE
BACK ROWS AND DEALING WITH IT,
IF A LOVED ONE SEES A YOUNG KID
WHO HAS SOME PROBLEMS, NOT JUST
PRETEND THEY DON'T EXIST, THERE
ARE MEDICAL TREATMENTS.
>> AND ALSO OFTEN TIMES PARENTS
CAN'T GET HELP UNLESS THE CHILD
CAN BE PROVEN TO BE A DANGER TO
THEMSELVES OR OTHERS.
AND THAT OFTEN WAITS UNTIL A
CRIME IS COMMITTED.
>> AND WE DON'T KNOW ENOUGH
ABOUT THE SHOOTER IN THIS CASE,
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT KIND OF
INDIVIDUALS THIS INDIVIDUAL MAY
OR MAY NOT HAVE HAD.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT KIND OF
TREATMENT HE MAY OR MAY NOT HAVE
HAD.
I SUSPECT WE'RE GOING TO LEARN A
LOT MORE.
>>> VICTORIA SOTO IS BEING
REMEMBERED AS A HERO AS WELL.
SHE DIED FRIDAY MORNING TRYING
TO PROTECT HER FIRST GRADE
STUDENTS.
JUST HEAD YOU'RE GOING TO HEAR
FROM NICOLE AND STEVEN WHOSE
DAUGHTER WAS IN THE CLASSROOM
ACROSS THE HALL.
THEIR DAUGHTER WHO SURVIVED AND
IS OKAY.
WAS A STUDENT OF VICTORIA SOTO'S
LAST YEAR.
THEY BELIEVE SHE'S ALIVE TONIGHT
BECAUSE OF VICTORIA SOTO.
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
TO THE BEST VACATION
SP(ALL) THE GULF!
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHICH OF
OUR GREAT STATES FOLKS VISIT.
MISSISSIPPI,
ALABAMA,
LOUISIANA
OR FLORIDA,
THEY'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
SHAUL, YOUR ALABAMA
HOSPITALITY IS INCREDIBLE.
THANKS, KAREN.
LOVE YOUR MISSISSIPPI OUTDOORS.
I VOTE FOR YOUR
FLORIDA BEACHES, DAWN.
BILL, THIS LOUISIANA
SEAFOOD IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR ON THE GULF,
WE'VE DECIDED TO PUT
ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
NOW IS THE PERFECT TIME TO
VISIT ANYONE OF OUR STATES.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE, GO FISHING
OR JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
WE'VE GOT COASTLINE TO EXPLORE
AND WILDLIFE TO PHOTOGRAPH.
AND THERE'S WORLD CLASS DINING
WITH OUR WORLD FAMOUS SEAFOOD.
SO FOR A GREAT VACATION
THIS YEAR, COME TO THE GULF.
ITS ALL FABULOUS BUT
I GIVE FLORIDA THE EDGE.
RIGHT AFTER MISSISSIPPI.
YOU MEAN ALABAMA.
SAY LOUISIANOR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
THIS INVITATION IS
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP
AND ALL OF US WHO
CALL THE GULF HOME.
>>> IT'S IMPORTANT TO REMEMBER
THERE WERE HUNDREDS OF CHILDREN
INSIDE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL FRIDAY MORNING.
THEIR PARENTS RACED TO THE SCENE
DESPERATE TO FIND THEIR SONS AND
DAUGHTERS.
NICOLE AND STEVEN MADDOX LIVED
THROUGH THAT PANIC.
THEIR DAUGHTER JORDAN IS A
SECOND GRADER, THANKFULLY THEY
FOUND HER SAFE.
HER CLASSROOM WAS JUST ACROSS
THE HALL FROM VICTORIA SOTO'S
FIRST GRADE CLASSROOM.
VICTORIA SOTO DIED TRYING TO
SAVE HER STUDENTS.
SHE IS 27 YEARS OLD AND IS BEING
REMEMBERED TONIGHT AS A HERO.
I SPOKE A SHORT TIME AGO TO
NICOLE AND STEVEN MADDOX.
>> HOW ARE YOU GUYS HOLDING UP,
HOW IS JORDAN HOLDING UP?
>> I THINK WE'RE DOING OKAY.
WE HAVEN'T HAD A CHANCE TO
PROCESS EVERYTHING.
WE'RE TRYING TO BE THERE FOR
HER, AND SUPPORT HER, AND HELP
HER TO DEAL WITH THIS IN HER OWN
WAY AND OWN TIME.
SHE'S DOING OKAY, IT'S JUST THE
NIGHTTIME I THINK IS WHEN SHE
REALLY STARTS TO REFLECT ON
EVERYTHING THAT HAPPENED.
>> THERE'S SO MANY PARENTS
AROUND, NOT ONLY THIS TOWN, BUT
AROUND THE WORLD WHO ARE TRYING
TO FIGURE OUT HOW TO TALK TO
THEIR KIDS ABOUT IT, HOW DO
YOU -- DO YOU WAIT FOR JORDAN TO
SAY SOMETHING TO YOU?
HOW DO YOU DEAL WITH IT?
>> I THINK THAT'S KIND OF WHAT
WE'VE BEEN DOING.
JUST BECAUSE WHO KNOWS HOW TO
DEAL WITH SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
AS THINGS COME UP, SHE ASKS
QUESTIONS, YOU ANSWER THEM
CALMLY.
WHAT HAS --
>> WHAT DID SHE SEE, DO YOU
KNOW?
>> OR HEAR?
>> WE'VE BEEN GETTING THE STORY
SLOWLY FROM HER.
THE FIRST TIME SHE TOLD US THE
STORY, SHE TOLD US ABOUT HEARING
THE GUNSHOTS.
HER CLASSROOM IS RIGHT BEHIND
THE PRINCIPAL'S OFFICE AND THE
CONFERENCE ROOM THAT I
UNDERSTAND SOME OF THE FOLKS
WERE IN.
>> SHE WAS RIGHT ACROSS THE HALL
FROM VICTORIA SOTO'S CLASS?
>> WHICH IS SOMETHING SHE WAS
EXCITED ABOUT, SHE WOULD BE
GOING JUST ACROSS THE HALL FROM
HER FAVORITE TEACHER.
THEY SPOKE ALMOST DAILY.
AND THAT WAS THE HARDEST THING
TO HAVE TO TELL HER.
THAT'S WHEN SHE REALLY BROKE
DOWN.
SHE HAD BEEN HANDLING MOST OF IT
OKAY, BUT WHEN WE TOLD HER ABOUT
MISS SOTO THAT'S WHEN SHE TOOK
IT THE HARDEST.
>> SHE KNOWS SHE'S DEAD?
>> SHE KNOWS NOW.
WE WAITED.
WE TOLD HER SATURDAY MORNING.
>> HOW DO YOU SAY THAT TO A
6-YEAR-OLD?
>> WE JUST EXPLAINED TO HER, YOU
KNOW WHAT HAPPENED YESTERDAY.
AND HONESTLY SHE SAW ENOUGH TO
UNDERSTAND THAT THERE WERE
PEOPLE THAT DIDN'T WALK OUT OF
THERE ALIVE.
>> SHE SAW SOMEBODY LAYING
THERE?
>> SHE SAW THE PRINCIPAL, YEAH.
THEY HAD TO WALK THE CHILDREN
OUT THROUGH THE FRONT DOOR WHERE
HER CLASSROOM IS LOCATED.
SHE WALKED PAST THE BODY.
ALTHOUGH THEY TOLD THEM TO CLOSE
THEIR EYES, I THINK SOME OF THEM
WERE KIND OF PEEKING AS KIDS
HAVE A TENDENCY TO DO.
>> SHE SAW THE PRINCIPAL ON THE
FLOOR?
>> SHE SAW THE PRINCIPAL, SHE
SAW BLOOD, SHE TOLD US ABOUT A
LOT OF BROKEN GLASS.
>> SO WHEN YOU ACTUALLY TOLD HER
THAT HER FORMER TEACHER HAD
DIED, HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN THAT?
>> UNFORTUNATELY, IT'S VERY
SIMPLE.
IT'S -- WE CALM SAID, JORDAN,
SHE WAS ONE OF THE TEACHERS WHO
PASSED AWAY.
SHE HAD A MOMENT WHERE SHE
PAUSED AND HER EYES GOT REAL
WIDE, AND SHE JUST -- YOU COULD
SEE HER HEART SINK.
AND --
>> DOES A 6-YEAR-OLD KNOW -- I
MEAN, MY DAD DIED WHEN I WAS 10.
I'M NOT SURE LOOKING BACK ON IT,
THAT I UNDERSTOOD FULLY WHAT
THAT MEANT AT THE TIME.
>> I THINK CHILDREN ARE
RESILIENT AND THEY CAN HEAR THE
COLD HARD TRUTH OF SOMETHING AND
TAKE THAT IN.
IT MAY TAKE YEARS TO PROCESS,
BUT MY ADVICE TO PARENTS IS
DON'T TRY TO COVER IT UP OR --
WHEN DEATH HAPPENS OR HORRIBLE
THINGS HAPPEN, YOU HAVE TO FIND
A WAY TO EXPLAIN IT TO YOUR
CHILDREN.
IN A LOT OF WAYS, IT'S LIFE.
THIS IS THE WORLD WE LIVE IN.
AND THERE'S EVIL AND HIDING THAT
DOES NOT HELP THEM AT ALL.
>> SHE MUST HAVE -- I THINK THE
ULTIMATE REALITY -- SHE LOOKED
AT US AND SAID, WHO AM I GOING
TO TALK TO EVERY DAY?
I SAID THERE ARE OTHER TEACHERS
YOU CAN TALK TO.
SHE SAID YEAH, BUT SHE WAS
REALLY FUNNY.
>> WHAT WAS IT ABOUT HER?
>> SHE WAS A KIND INDIVIDUAL,
YOU CAN TELL SHE HAD A HEART FOR
HER CHILDREN, EACH AND EVERY ONE
OF THEM.
SHE MEANT BUSINESS, WHICH WE
LOVED.
>> SHE WAS YOUTHFUL.
OUR FIRST TEACHER CONFERENCE I
FELT LIKE AN OLD MAN.
SHE SEEMED BARELY OUT OF HIGH
SCHOOL HERSELF.
IT'S JUST A TESTAMENT TO HER
PERSONALITY.
>> VERY MATURE.
SHE WAS A GREAT TEACHER AND SHE
PUT EVERYTHING INTO WHAT SHE
DID.
THE KIDS ENJOYED LEARNING.
THERE WASN'T A DAY THAT JORDAN
SAID I DON'T WANT TO GO TO
SCHOOL.
THERE WERE TIMES IT SEEMED LIKE
AFTER A WEEKEND SHE WAS EXCITED
TO GO BACK.
THAT TOLD US SHE HAD A REALLY
GOOD TEACHER.
SOMEBODY WHO WAS DOING THEIR JOB
AND DOING IT WELL.
>> THANK YOU FOR TALKING TO US.
I KNOW IT'S NOT EASY, I
APPRECIATE IT.
>> THANK YOU.
>> I WISH YOU PEACE IN THE DAYS
AHEAD.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> COMING UP, YOU'RE GOING TO
HEAR FROM A SUNDAY SCHOOLTEACHER
HERE IN NEWTOWN, WHO'S TRYING TO
HELP HER YOUNG STUDENTS DEAL
WITH THIS TRAGEDY.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[ Male Announcer ] THIS IS
JOE WOODS' FIRST DAY OF WORK.
AND HIS NEW BOSS TOLD HIM
TWO THINGS --
COOK WHAT YOU LOVE,
AND SAVE YOUR MONEY.
JOE DOESN'T KNOW IT YET,
BUT HE'LL WORK HIS WAY UP
FROM BUSSER TO WAITER TO CHEF
BEFORE OPENING A RESTAURANT
SPECIALIZING IN FISH AND GAME
FROM THE GREAT NORTHWEST.
HE'LL START INVESTING EARLY,
HE'LL FIND SOME GOOD PEOPLE
TO HELP GUIDE HIM,
AND HE'LL SET MONEY ASIDE
FROM HIS FIRST DAY OF WORK
TO HIS LAST,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
YOU'LL ALSO CARE ABOUT
OUR NEW OFFER.
YOU GET ACCESS TO NURSES WHO
CAN HELP WITH YOUR QUESTIONS.
AND YOUR LOVED ONE CAN GET
EXELON PATCH FREE FOR 30 DAYS.
IF THE DOCTOR FEELS
IT'S RIGHT FOR THEM.
IT CANNOT CHANGE
HOW THE DISEASE PROGRESSES.
HOSPITALIZATION
AND RARELY DEATH
HAVE BEEN REPORTED IN PATIENTS
WHO WORE MORE THAN ONE PATCH
AT A TIME.
THE MOST COMMON SIDE EFFECTS
OF EXELON PATCH
ARE NAUSEA, VOMITING,
AND DIARRHEA.
THE LIKELIHOOD AND SEVERITY
OF THESE SIDE EFFECTS
MAY INCREASE
AS THE DOSE INCREASES.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
LOSS OF APPETITE OR WEIGHT.
PATIENTS WHO WEIGH
LESS THAN 110 POUNDS
MAY EXPERIENCE
MORE SIDE EFFECTS.
PEOPLE AT RISK
FOR STOMACH ULCERS
WHO TAKE CERTAIN
OTHER MEDICINES
SHOULD TALK TO THEIR DOCTOR
BECAUSE SERIOUS
STOMACH PROBLEMS
SUCH AS BLEEDING MAY WORSEN.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
SLOW HEART RATE.
THIRTY DAYS OF EXELON PATCH
FREE FOR YOUR LOVED ONE.
ACCESS TO TRAINED NURSES
FOR YOU.
CALL 1-855-999-1399
OR VISIT EXELONPATCHOFFER2.COM.
>>> SHE WAS THE TYPE OF PERSON
THAT COULD LIGHT UP THE ROOM.
SHE ALWAYS HAD SOMETHING KIND TO
SAY ABOUT ANYBODY.
HER LOVE AND THE STRENGTH THAT
SHE GAVE US, AND THE EXAMPLE
THAT SHE SHOWED US IS
REMARKABLE.
SHE IS AN INCREDIBLE PERSON.
AND I'M SO BLESSED TO BE HER
DAD.
>> THAT WAS ROBBIE PARKER
TALKING ABOUT HIS DAUGHTER
EMILIE WHO WAS 6 YEARS OLD, SHE
DIED ON SATURDAY.
THE FAMILY MEETING TONIGHT WITH
PRESIDENT OBAMA AT THE SCHOOL.
FROM THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES, FRIENDS OR HOUSES OF
WORSHIP HERE, MEMBERS OF THIS
COMMUNITY ARE SEEKING SOLACE ALL
WEEKEND.
THIS MORNING, SOME OF THE
CHILDREN SURVIVED THE SHOOTING,
WENT TO SUNDAY SCHOOL JUST LIKE
THEY DID EVERY WEEK, IT SOUNDS
LIKE A SIMPLE THING, WASN'T
SIMPLE OR EASY FOR ANYONE.
NOT FOR THE CHILDREN OR THEIR
TEACHER.
>> Reporter: THIS IS WHERE SOME
OF THE CHILDREN WHO WERE KILLED
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY PRAYED
AND WENT TO SUNDAY SCHOOL.
SHE WAS BACK ON THIS SUNDAY FOR
ALL HER STUDENTS, INCLUDING
THOSE WHO SURVIVED.
>> YOU HAD A LOT OF CHILDREN
HERE IN THIS ROOM, WHAT WAS THAT
LIKE FOR YOU.
>> IT WAS A LITTLE BIT -- IT WAS
VERY SCARY, BECAUSE I SPENT
YESTERDAY TRYING TO PREPARE FOR
TODAY.
BUT YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT'S GOING
TO HAPPEN.
AND RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE A CHILD
RAISED THEIR HAND.
I SAID YES, AND THEY SAID, MY
FRIENDS DIED.
LATER ON WHEN WE GOT TO THE
POINT WHERE WE PRAYED, PRETTY
MUCH EVERY CHILD IN HERE HAD A
PRAYER, AND MANY OF THEM WERE MY
FRIEND JACK DIED, MY FRIEND BEN
DIED, MY FRIEND CHARLOTTE DIED.
WE PRAYED, WE PROBABLY PRAYED
MORE THAN WE'VE EVER PRAYED
BEFORE.
>> SHE KNEW THERE WOULD BE
ANXIETY AMONG THE CHILDREN AND
THEIR PARENTS.
SHE SAW BOTH.
>> WE WERE A LITTLE WORRIED.
WE HAD KIDS WHOSE PARENTS SAID
THEY DIDN'T WANT TO COME TO
CLASS.
IT'S LIKE A SCHOOL AND THEY WERE
WORRIED.
ONE GIRL DIDN'T WANT TO COME
BECAUSE BEN WOULDN'T BE THERE.
THERE WAS A LOT OF ANXIETY.
BEN WOULD HAVE BEEN SITTING
RIGHT HERE ON THIS CARPET WITH
ME.
SO WHEN THE KIDS BRING IT UP
THAT MY FRIEND BEN DIED, I HAD
TO DO THE ATTENDANCE, WE HAVE
ATTENDANCE SIGN IN PAGES FOR THE
PARENTS.
THEY HAVE TO SIGN THEM IN AND
OUT.
AS I WAS PUTTING THEM IN THE BOX
LAST NIGHT, THE FIRST GRADE PAGE
HAD BEN'S NAME ON IT.
I THOUGHT, THIS IS GOING TO BE
HANGING ON THE HALL WALL WITH
HIS NAME ON IT, AND HE WOULDN'T
BE SIGNED IN.
SO I PRINTED IT WITH HIS NAME
OFF.
AND WHEN I TALKED TO THE PASTOR
ABOUT IT, IT REALLY HIT ME, I
ERASED HIS NAME.
>> THIS ONE SAYS CHARLOTTE IS
SAFE.
>> YES.
THAT WAS FOR CHARLOTTE WHO WENT
HERE.
>> CHARLOTTE WAS 6 YEARS OLD.
ANOTHER CARD READS IN PART
YOU'RE NOT ALONE.
VOGELMAN SAYS SHE FELT PRIDE, A
STRENGTH SHE SAW IN HER SUNDAY
SCHOOL CHILDREN.
>> I'VE BEEN WORKING WITH KIDS
MY WHOLE ADULT LIFE.
THEY'RE MY KIDS, THEY'RE MY
KIDS.
PEOPLE ON FACEBOOK ARE LIKE, I'M
SO GLAD YOUR KIDS ARE OKAY.
I'M OFFYOUSLY VERY KIDS THAT MY
KIDS ARE NOT OKAY, BUT MY KIDS
ARE NOT OKAY, MY KIDS DIED,
THAT'S HOW EVERYONE FEELS IN
NEWTOWN.
SORRY.
THEY'RE BABYIES.
>> I MEAN, FACED WITH THAT
HORRIBLE DILEMMA WHETHER TO TAKE
THE CHILD'S NAME OFF THE BOARD,
HOW IS SHE DOING THROUGH ALL
THIS.
>> TAKING THAT NAME DOWN, THAT'S
BEEN THE MOMENT FOR HER.
EVERYONE'S HAD A MOMENT.
THE WAY SHE'S GETTING THROUGH IT
IS STRANGELY ENOUGH THE CHILDREN
THEMSELVES, THEIR HONESTY, THEY
KNOW THEY HAVE TO BE STRONG FOR
THESE CHILDREN.
RECEIVING ALL THESE KIND WORDS
FROM PEOPLE ALL OVER THE WORLD,
THAT'S BEEN A SOURCE OF
ENCOURAGEMENT.
SHE WAS WONDERING WHAT SHE WAS
GOING TO DO FOR THE LESSON
TODAY, WHAT SHE WAS GOING TO SAY
TO THESE CHILDREN.
SHE GOT A KIND LETTER FROM
SOMEONE FROM LITTLETON COLORADO,
FROM THE CLERGY THERE, THEY
OBVIOUSLY HAVE BEEN THROUGH A
LOT.
ONLY WHEN YOU HAVE BEEN THROUGH
IT, CAN YOU OFFER THE ADVICE TO
GET THROUGH IT THIS TIME.
>> HOPEFULLY HER FAITH IS
GETTING HER THROUGH AS WELL.
REMARKABLE.
>>> WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
THERE'S A HEALTH COMPANY THAT
CAN HELP YOU STAY THAT WAY.
WHAT'S HEALTHIER THAN THAT?