>>> STORIES IN THE NEWSROOM,
SCHOOLKIDS IN NEWTOWN GO BACK TO
SCHOOL.
HOW TEACHERS ARE PREPARING FOR
WHAT'S SURE TO BE A TRYING DAY.
AFTER THE NEWTOWN TRAGEDY IS THE
COUNTRY FINALLY READY FOR
STRICTER GUN LAWS?
MANY FORMER PRO GUN LAWMAKERS
SAY YES, BUT WE STILL HAVE NOT
HEARD FROM THE NRA.
>>> ONE OF THE NEW THINGS THE
SCHOOL SHOOTER MAY HAVE DONE
SOCIALLY WAS PLAY VIDEO GAMES.
SO IS THERE A LINK BETWEEN THESE
TYPES OF GAMES AND AGGRESSIVE
BEHAVIOR?
ONE EXPERT SAYS YES.
"NEWSROOM" STARTS NOW.
GOOD MORNING.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US
TODAY.
I'M CAROL COSTELLO IN ATLANTA.
FIRST A SMALL STEP TOWARD
NORMALLY IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
SOLEDAD O'BRIEN JOINS US LIVE.
GOOD MORNING, SOLEDAD.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING TO
YOU, CAROL.
AS YOU SAID, CLASSES RESUME
TODAY FOR MOST OF THE KIDS IN
THIS COMMUNITY, SO MANY
WRESTLING WITH SO MUCH
HEARTBREAK, ALL OF THE NEWTOWN
SCHOOLS EXCEPT FOR SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY WILL REOPEN.
GRIEF AND THE FEARS OF RETURNING
STUDENTS AN ADDITIONAL CONCERN.
POLICE OFFICERS WILL BE AT EVERY
SINGLE SCHOOL AND TODAY THE TOWN
WILL LAY TO REST, THE
GRANDMOTHER OF CHARLOTTE BACON
SAYS HER 6-YEAR-OLD
GRANDDAUGHTER WAS A BUNDLE OF
ENERGY WHO LOVED DRESSES AND A
SECOND, JESSICA REKOS, LOVED
HORSES, SHE WROTE HER OWN HORSE
STORIES, EXCITED ABOUT A PAIR OF
COWGIRL BOOTS SHE WAS EXPECTING
TO GET FOR CHRISTMAS.
NOW TO GET THE LATEST ON THE
SCHOOL'S REOPENING THIS MORNING,
SARA ENDO IS HERE IN THE HEART
OF NEWTOWN WITH MORE.
>> Reporter: THEY'RE STARTING TO
SEE A LOT OF SCHOOL BUSES
ROLLING BY AND IN ABOUT AN HOUR
OR TWO CLASSES WILL BE IN
SESSION.
THEY ALL MAY BE ANXIOUS ABOUT
SCHOOL RETURNING BACK TO
NORMALCY BUT THIS COULD BE THE
FIRST STEP TO HEALING.
STEP TOWARDS NORMALCY, FOR
NEWTON KIDS THAT MEANS GO BACK
TO SCHOOL.
>> WE'RE A LITTLE BIT WORRIED
BECAUSE WE KNOW WHAT WE THOUGHT
WAS A SECURE SCHOOL HAD THIS
HAPPEN TO THEM.
>> Reporter: FACING FEAR MAY BE
THE FIRST STEP TO OVERCOME THIS
TRAGEDY.
>> CHILDREN HAVE TO GET BACK TO
SCHOOL.
IF WE LET THIS SORT OF TERROR IN
OUR LIVES IN THIS COUNTRY, WE
HAVE TOE GET OUR KIDS BACK TO
CLASS.
>> Reporter: EXCEPT FOR THOSE AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
MONDAY ALL SCHOOLS WERE CLOSED
AS TEACHERS AND ADMINISTRATORS
TRAINED WITH EXPERTS ON HOW TO
HANDLE THE AFTERMATH.
MANY PARENTS AGREE KIDS BELONG
BACK IN SCHOOL.
>> I THINK THAT ONE OF THE BIG
THINGS WE HAVE TO DO IS HAVE
SOME SORT OF NORMALCY AND SCHOOL
IS PART OF THAT, UNFORTUNATELY,
YOU KNOW, WE'RE LIVING IN THIS
WORLD WHERE SOMETIMES EVIL
PREVAILS SOMETIMES, BUT WE'RE
JUST BELIEVING THAT GOOD WILL
OVERCOME THIS.
>> SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY REMAINS
A CRIME SCENE.
FURNITURE AND SUPPLIES WERE
MOVED TO CHALK HILL MIDDLE
SCHOOL WHERE SANDY HOOK STUDENTS
WILL EVENTUALLY RESUME CLASSES.
>> WHENEVER THE STOOL HAS
STARTED THEY'LL TALK INTO A
CLASSROOM THAT LOOKS AS CLOSE AS
POSSIBLE AS THEIR CLASSROOM THAT
THEY LEFT.
>> GRIEF COUNSELORS AND POLICE
OFFICERS WILL BE PRESENT AT
NEWTOWN SCHOOLS TODAY AND
THROUGHOUT THE WEEK.
PRINCIPLES ASK PARENTS TO TALK
TO THEIR KIDS BEFORE THEY GO
BACK TO SCHOOLS AND THE TEACHER
ALSO ADDRESS WHAT HAPPENED HERE
IN AN AGE APPROPRIATE MANNER.
SOLEDAD?
>> SANDRA ENDO, THANK YOU.
INVESTIGATORS CONTINUE TO SEARCH
THE HOME OF ADAM LANZA.
WE'LL LEARN MORE ABOUT HOW HIS
MOTHER, NANCY, MIGHT HAVE BEEN
STORING THE WEAPONS HE USED IN
THE SHOOTING.
CNN'S DEB FEYERICK IS AT THE
HOUSE AND JOINS US WITH MORE.
GOOD MORNING.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING,
SOLEDAD.
INVESTIGATORS ARE TRYING TO
UNLOCK THE MYSTERIES INSIDE THIS
GUY'S MIND, TRYING TO DO IT BY
PUTTING TOGETHER SHARDS OF A
BROKEN COMPUTER AND THAT IS WHAT
IS GOING TO TAKE A RELATIVELY
LONG TIME YESTERDAY AT THIS HOME
A NUMBER OF INVESTIGATORS WERE
HERE FOR THE BETTER PART OF THE
AFTERNOON ABOUT TWO AND A HALF
HOURS FOUR INVESTIGATORS IN
UNMARKED PATROL CARS, THEY CAME
QUIETLY, LEFT QUIETLY.
WE COULD NOT TELL WHETHER THEY
WERE CARRYING ANYTHING.
ADAM LANZA APPEARS TO HAVE
FALLEN OFF THE GRID.
THREE YEARS UNACCOUNTED FOR.
LAST TIME ANY RECORD OF HIM WAS
BACK IN 2009 WHEN HE WAS A
STUDENT AT A LOCAL STUDENT,
TAKING SEVERAL CLASSES.
AFTER 2009 HE FALLS AWAY.
NOBODY NLDS WHAT HE WAS DOING
OVER THE LAST COUPLE OF YEARS.
YOU LOOK AT THIS PICTURE PERFECT
HOUSE ON THE HILL YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT WAS GOING ON INSIDE THIS
HOUSE.
YOU KNOW THE MOTHER WAS KILLED
NEAR HER HOME AND EARLIER THIS
MORNING SOLEDAD WE HAVE TO TELL
YOU THAT SOME OF THE FAMILIES OF
THE CHILDREN WHO WERE KILLED,
THEY LIVE NOT TOO FAR FROM THIS
HOME AND WE SAW SEVERAL CARS
LEAVING A HOUSE AND THE FAMILY
VISIBLY UPSET INSIDE, WE COULD
TELL, THERE WAS A SCHOOLBUS AS
WELL BUT THIS COMMUNITY STILL
FEELING THIS AS INVESTIGATORS
TRY HOPEFULLY TO GET SOME
INDICATION AS TO WHAT HE WAS
THINKING AND WHY HE CHOSE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY.
SOLEDAD?
>> Reporter: IT'S TERRIBLE.
THIS SHOOTING REIGNITED I THINK
IT'S FAIR TO SAY GUN CONTROL.
YOU HAVE ONE OF THE LARGEST
SPORTING GOODS RETAILERS IN THE
WORLD HALTING ITS SALE OF SOME
KINDS OF THOSE SEMIAUTOMATIC
WEAPONS, RIGHT?
>> YES, AS A MATTER OF FACT
THAT'S EXACTLY RIGHT.'S SPORTING
GOODS STORE ARE STOPPING GUN
SALES IN THE STORE CLOSEST TO
NEWTOWN, THE STORE IN DANBURY,
COUNTRY COUNTRY AND THE PRIVATE
EQUITY FIRM CERBERUS DECIDED TO
SELL OFF THE COMPANY THAT MAKES
THE BUSHMASTER, ONE OF THE
RIVALS USED IN THIS HORRIBLE
ATTACK.
THAT RIFLE INFLICTED MAXIMUM
DAMAGE ON A NUMBER OF THE
VICTIMS SO THERE ARE CHANGES
THAT ARE GOING ON RIGHT NOW AS
SPORTING GOODS STORES AND GUN
SELLERS AS THEY BEGIN TO
REEVALUATE HOW MUCH OF A STAKE
THEY WANT IN THE FIREARMS SALE
IN THE UNITED STATES.
>> IT'S INTERESTING.
ALL RIGHT, DEB FEYERICK, THANK
YOU, APPRECIATE IT.
LET'S GET BACK TO CAROL
COSTELLO.
>> DICK'S SPORTING GOODS ISN'T
THE ONLY STORE CURTAILING SOME
GUN SOLES.
WALMART IS AS WELL.
ALISON KOSIK, GOOD MORNING.
>> GOOD MORNING.
WALMART IS NO LONGERIZING THE
BUSHMASTER AR-15 BUT THE
RETAILER SAYS YOU CAN BUY IT AT
SELECT LOCATIONS.
WALMART IS ONE OF THE BIGGEST
GUN DEALERS IN THE WORLD AND
HIGH CAPACITIES AND GUNS LIKE
SEMIAUTOMATIC MILITARY STYLE
RIFLES ARE THE FASTEST GROWING
IN THE MARKET.
YOU LOOK AT WALMART'S
ADVERTISING, THE BUSHMASTER IS
NO LONGER LISTED, NOT ON BASS
PRO SHOP BUT YOU CAN STILL VIEW
IT ON CABELL'S.
RETAILERS ARE TRYING TO DISTANCE
THEMSELVES FROM THE TRAGEDY.
>> BIG STORES ARE DISTANCING
THEMSELVES, BUT SMALLER BEEN
STORES ACROSS ITS COUNTRY, SOME
OF THOSE SAY PEOPLE ARE BUYING
GUNS LIKE MAD.
>> YOU LOOK AT GUN SALES THEY'VE
BEEN UP OVER THE PAST FEW DAYS
AND IN SOME WAY IT'S NOT A HUGE
SURPRISE.
SOME PEOPLE WANT TO PROTECT
THEMSELVES AND GUNSHOP OWNERS
SAY THEY ARE WORRIED ABOUT GUN
CONTROL LAWS AFTER THE PRESIDENT
SUNDAY SIGNALED THE POSSIBLY FOR
MORE ACTION, IT'S PRESSURING,
GETTING PEOPLE TO BUY GUNS AND
BUY WEAPONS NOW BEFORE A
POSSIBLE CRACKDOWN CAN HAPPEN
AND YOU COULD ALSO SEE
PRESSURING STOCKS AND COMPANIES
THAT MAKE THE GUNS LIKE SIT AMI
WESSON, SHARES TUMBLED MONDAY
AND POINTING TO A LOWER OPEN
TODAY.
>>ALSON KOSC KOSIK ON THE BUSIN
SIDE OF THIS TODAY.
>>> TODAY WE ARE BILLIONS CLOSER
TO REACHING A DEAL.
PRESIDENT OBAMA TUFRD COMPROMISE
ON BOEHNER'S IDEA TO RAISE TAXES
ON PEOPLE MAKING $1 MILLION OR
MORE A YEAR.
THE PRESIDENT PROPOSED RAISING
TAXES ON FAMILY MAKING MORE THAN
$250,000 A YEAR.
DAN LOTHIAN IS AT THE WHITE
HOUSE.
THIS IS GOOD, RIGHT?
>> Reporter: WELL IT'S CERTAINLY
SIGNIFICANT BECAUSE AS YOU
POINTED OUT THE PRESIDENT FOR
QUITE SOME TIME HAD BEEN
CAMPAIGNING ON THE ISSUE SAYING
TAXES HAD TO GO UP ON HOUSE
HOLDS MAKING MORE THAN $250,000
DURING THESE NEGOTIATIONS OVER
THE LAST SEVERAL WEEKS, BOTH THE
PRESIDENT AND OTHER AIDS HERE AT
THE WHITE HOUSE HAD BEEN
INSISTING THERE WOULD BE NO DEAL
UNLESS TAXES WENT UP ON THOSE
MAKING MORE THAN 250,000 AND NOW
THE PRESIDENT ACCORDING TO
SOURCE
SOURCES LAYING OUT THE PROPOSAL
TO RAISE IT TO 400,000.
IT IS SIGNIFICANT, NOT WHAT
REPUBLICANS REALLY WANT.
THEY DON'T WANT TAXES GOING UP
ON ANYONE.
THEY WANT THE TAX BREAKS TO
CONTINUE FOR ALL AMERICANS
BECAUSE THEY BELIEVE THIS COULD
HAVE AN ADVERSE EFFECT ON THE
ECONOMY, COULD IMPACT THE JOB
CREATORS.
IN ADDITION THE PRESIDENT MADE
ANOTHER CONCESSION RATHER
OFFERING UP $1.2 TRILLION IN NEW
REVENUE AND $1.2 TRILLION IN
SPENDING CUTS.
THIS WAS SOMETHING SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER HAD BEEN INSISTENT UPON,
BALANCE OF NEW SPENDING CUTS AND
NEW REVENUE ALTHOUGH HOUSE GOP
AIDES SAY THEY HAVE TROUBLE WITH
THE MATH BUT THEY BELIEVE THIS
IS A MOVE IN THE RIGHT
DIRECTION.
>> TALK ABOUT THE FREQUENCY OF
MEETINGS BETWEEN JOHN BOEHNER
AND PRESIDENT OBAMA.
THE LAST EIGHT DAYS THEY MET
THREE TIMES?
>> THAT'S RIGHT, THEY WERE MET
THREE TIMES.
YESTERDAY'S MEETING HAPPENED
HERE AT THE WHITE HOUSE, LASTED
ABOUT 45 MINUTES.
WE WERE NOT TOLD WHEN THAT
MEETING STARTED.
WE GOT WORD OF THAT MEETING
AFTER IT HAD BEEN UNDER WAY FOR
10 OR 15 MINUTES.
THEY'VE HAD THE THREE
FACE-TO-FACE MEETINGS AND
INDICATIONS FROM THE WHITE HOUSE
THE OFFER THE PRESIDENT PUT
FORWARD IS NOT THE FINAL SUFR
THERE'S ADDITIONAL ROOM FOR
COMPROMISE.
NO WORD OF ANY ADDITIONAL
MEETINGS OR PHONE CALLS TODAY.
>> WE MAY HAVE A CHRISTMAS
SURPRISE, WHO KNOWS.
>>> FIVE DAYS AFTER THEIR
CAPTURE AN AMERICAN JOURNALIST
AND HIS PRODUCTION CREW ARE
SAFELY OUT OF SYRIA.
NBC'S CHIEF FOREIGN
CORRESPONDENT RICHARD ENGEL AND
HIS CREW DISAPPEARED THURSDAY
AFTER CROSSING INTO NORTHWEST
SYRIA FROM TURKEY.
THIS MORNING HE TOLD THE "TODAY"
SHOW HOW THEY WERE ALL FINALLY
SET FREE.
>> AT THE END OF THIS, WE WERE
BEING MOVED TO YET ANOTHER
LOCATION IN THE LATER AROUND
11:00 LAST NIGHT LOCAL TIME AND
AS WE WERE MOVING ALONG THE ROAD
THE KIDNAPPERS CAME ACROSS A
REBEL CHECKPOINT, SOMETHING THEY
HADN'T EXPECTED SO WE WERE IN
THE BACK OF WHAT YOU'D THINK OF
AS A MINI VAN AND AS WE WERE
DRIVING ALONG THE ROAD THE
KIDNAPPERS SAW THIS CHECKPOINT,
STARTED A GUN FIGHT WITH IT.
TWO OF THE KIDNAPPERS WERE
KILLED, THEY CLIMBED OUT OF THE
VEHICLE AND THE REBELS TOOK US.
WE SPENT THE NIGHT WITH THEM, WE
DIDN'T GET MUCH SLEEP.
>> IVAN WATSON JOINS US FROM
ISTANBUL, TURKEY.
IVAN, WHO WERE THESE KIDNAPPERS
AND WHY DID THEY TAKE ME SEE
JOURNALISTS?
>> WELL, ACCORDING TO RICHARD
ENGEL'S STATEMENT THIS WAS A
SHABIHA PRO-GOVERNMENT MILITIA
MADE UP OF SHIITE MUSLIMS AND IT
GIVES YOU A SENSE OF HOW CHAOTIC
THE SITUATION HAS GOTTEN INSIDE
SYRIA.
WE WERE HEARING ABOUT CLASHES
BETWEEN RIFLE REBEL GROUPS.
WE'VE HEARD FROM SOME PEOPLE
INVOLVED IN TRYING TO LOCATE
RICHARD ENGEL'S TEAM THAT THE
GUYS WHO GRABBED HIM WERE
CLAIMING TO BE MEMBERS OF THE
FREE SYRIAN ARMY, THE REBEL
MOVEMENT THAT IS FIGHTING TO
OVERTHROW BASHAR AL ASSAD.
IT GIVES YOU A SENSE OF HOW
CHAOTIC THE POLITICAL LANDSCAPE
IS WITH MANY ARMED GROUPS
CLAIMING TO BE REBELS, SOME
CLAIMING TO BE PARTS OF THE
GOVERNMENT AND SOME OUTLAWS OUT
FOR A RANSOM.
>> NBC NEVER CAME OUT PUBLICLY
AND SAID ENGEL OR HIS CREW WAS
MISSING.
THIS IS THE FIRST TIME WE'RE
HEARING ABOUT IT.
WHY DO YOU THINK THAT IS?
>> THIS IS A COMMON STRATEGY
USED IN THE CONFLICT ZONES WHEN
THERE HAVE BEEN HOSTAGE TAKINGS
AND KIDNAPPING.
AN EFFORT TO MAKE A MEDIA
BLACKOUT SO THAT PEOPLE CAN TRY
TO FIGURE OUT WHO IS MISSING,
WHO WERE THE ACTORS.
ARE THERE DEMANDS FROM THE
KIDNAPPERS AND TRY TO KEEP KIDS
ALIVE.
WE'VE SEEN THIS IN THE PAST IN
NUMEROUS DIFFERENT CONFLICT
ZONES AND THAT WAS USED IN THIS
CASE, TOO, WHILE NBC WAS TRYING
TO FIGURE OUT WHO TO TALK TO, TO
TRY TO GET THEIR PEOPLE BACK.
IT'S LIKELY TO BE A METHOD THIS
KIND OF MEDIA BLACKOUT WE'LL SEE
USED IN THE FUTURE AS WELL.
THERE HAVE BEEN OTHER
KIDNAPPINGS INSIDE SYRIA AND
NEGOTIATIONS SO WE'VE SEEN A
SIMILAR PAT PERSON IN THOSE
CASES.
ALSO THIS GIVES TIME FOR
COMPANIES AND COLLEAGUES TO
CONTACT FAMILY MEMBERS AND MAKE
SURE THAT THEY DO NOT GET THE
WRONG INFORMATION AND TRY TO
CONTROL THE DEVASTATING IMPACT
OF A TRAUMATIZING EXPERIENCE
LIKE THIS.
THANKFULLY RICHARD ENGEL AND
FOUR OF HIS COLLEAGUES ARE SAFE
RIGHT NOW, AND UNHARMED, AFTER
WHAT WAS A TERRIFYING EXPERIENCE
INVOLVING MOCK EXECUTIONS.
>> TOOK THE WORDS RIGHT OUT OF
MY MOUTH, IVAN WATSON REPORTING
LIVE THIS MORNING.
>>> AFTER THE TRAGEDY IN
NEWTOWN, RENEWED SUPPORT FOR
CHANGES IN AMERICA'S GUN LAWS
BUT WITH NATIONAL SUPPORT BEHIND
THE NATIONAL RIFLE ASSOCIATION
DO STRICTER GUN REGULATIONS
REALLY STAND A CHANCE?
HAVE A GOOD NIGHT.
HERE YOU GO. YOU, TOO.
I'M GOING TO DREAM
ABOUT THAT STEAK.
ABOUT THAT TIRAMISU.
WHAT A NIGHT, HUH?
BUT, UM, CAN THE TEST DRIVE
BE OVER NOW?
HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A PASSAT.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN, $0 DUE AT SIGNING,
$0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
>>> 17 MINUTES PAST THE HOUR,
WE'LL TAKE YOU BACK TO NEWTOWN
IN A MINUTE.
CALIFORNIA TEENAGER UNDER ARREST
ACCUSED OF THREATENING TO CARRY
OUT A SIMILAR ATTACK TO THE ONE
IN CONNECTICUT.
POLICE SAY SERGIO KAVAA
SUPPORTED THE ACTIONS OF THE
SCHOOL SHOOTER.
THE 18-YEAR-OLD NOW FACES FELONY
CHARGES OF CRIMINAL THREATS.
>>> WE'RE LEARNING NEW DETAILS
ABOUT THE MAN POLICE SAY SHOT
AND KILLED TWO PEOPLE IN AN
OREGON MALL BEFORE KILLING
HIMSELF.
JACOB ROBERTS' ROOMMATE TOLD
INVESTIGATORS THE GUNMAN ACTED
WEIRD AND STARTED TALKING ABOUT
MOVING AND SEG HIS POSSESSIONS
AND THE DAY BEFORE THE SHOOTING
ROBERTS TOLD A FRIEND HE NEEDED
TO GET OUT OF TOWN AND NEEDED A
GUN.
THE NEXT DAY BOTH ROBERTS AND A
RIFLE WERE MISSING.
>>> A NEW SATELLITE LAUNCHED BY
NORTH KOREA IS DEAD AND GONE
ACCORDING TO A U.S.
ASTROPHYSICIST WHO SAYS THE
SATELLITE IS NO LONGER GIVING
OFF ANY SIGNAL.
THE U.S. AND OTHER COUNTRIES
BELIEVE THE SATELLITE LAUNCH WAS
THE TEST OF A BALLISTIC MISSILE.
>>> IF YOU'RE PRAYING FOR LOWER
GAS PRICE THIS IS HOLIDAY SEASON
YOU MAY GET YOUR ANSWER.
ACCORDING TO AAA, GAS PRICES
HAVE BEEN FALLING EVERY DAY FOR
FOUR WEEKS.
THE PRICE IS THREE CENTS AWAY
FROM THE LOWEST MARK IN TWO
YEARS.
RIGHT NOW PRICES AVERAGE $3.24 A
GALLON.
>>> GUN CONTROL, IT JUST MAY BE
THE RIGHT TIME.
DEMOCRATIC LAWMAKERS WHO ARE
STRONGLY PRO GUN RIGHTS HAVE
SIGNALED THEY'RE WILLING TO DEAL
AND SENATOR DIANNE FEINSTEIN IS
READY WITH LEGISLATION.
>> THERE'S NO SECOND AMENDMENT
RIGHT TO BEAR EVERY TYPE OF
WEAPON THAT YOU KNOW OF.
THESE ARE A CERTAIN CLASS OF
WEAPONS.
THEY ARE DESIGNED TO KILL LARGE
NUMBERS OF PEOPLE IN CLOSE
COMB
COMBAT.
I DON'T BELIEVE THE SECOND
AMENDMENT COVERS THEM.
>> ADVOCATES LIKE NEW YORK MAYOR
MICHAEL BLOOMBERG ARE HOPEFUL,'
LONG WITH VICTIMS OF GUN
VIOLENCE CREATED A WEBSITE THAT
FEATURES PERSONAL TESTIMONIALS
OF HOW VIOLENCE HAS AFFECTED
THEIR LIVES.
STILL NO PUSHBACK FROM THE
POWERFUL GUN RIGHTS
ORGANIZATION, THE NRA, THE
NATIONAL RIFLE ORGANIZATION.
IT DOESN'T MEAN THE ORGANIZATION
ISN'T UP FOR A FIGHT.
IT'S A FAMILIAR RITUAL, SHOWING,
TELLING THEIR LOVE OF THE GUN.
>> HEY, I'M A CATHOLIC DEER
HUNTER.
I AM HAPPY TO BE CLINGING TO MY
GUNS AND MY RELIGION.
>> Reporter: DON'T THINK THIS
SORT OF THING IS LIMITED TO
GUN-LOVING REPUBLICANS.
DEMOCRATS RUN ON GUNS, TOO.
>> AS YOUR SENATOR I'LL PROTECT
OUR SECOND SNNT RIGHTS, THAT'S
WHY THE NRA ENDORSED ME.
>> Reporter: SANDY HOOK AND THE
INCOMPREHENSIBLE TRAGEDY TOUCHED
WEST VIRGINIA'S DEMOCRATIC
SENATOR JOE MANCHIN, A SUPPORTER
OF GUN RIGHTS.
>> WHO WOULD HAVE THOUGHT
ANYWHERE IN AMERICA OR IN THE
WORLD CHILDREN WOULD BE
SLAUGHTERED.
I DON'T KNOW OF ANYBODY THAT
GOES HUNTING WITH AN ASSAULT
RIFLE.
I DON'T KNOW PEOPLE THAT NEED
10, 20, 30-ROUND CLIPS.
>> SHAME ON THE NRA.
>> Reporter: GRASSROOTS
ORGANIZATIONS HAVE SPRUNG UP TO
MARCHING ON THE NRA BUT IT
REMAINS TO BE SEEN IF THIS WILL
TURN INTO LEGISLATIVE ACTION.
>> Reporter: SENATOR FEINSTEIN
SAYS SHE'LL INTRODUCE GUN
LEGISLATION IN THE NEXT FEW
WEEKS.
AS POLITICAL ANALYST LARRY
SABATO SAYS "THEY'RE LYING LOW.
THEY KNOW THEY CAN'T WIN AN
ARGUMENT WHEN THE EMOTION OF THE
SUBJECT IS COMPLETELY TILTED TO
THE OPPOSITION."
IT'S WHY SABATO SAYS SO FAR THE
NRA HAS NOT COMMENTED ON SANDY
POINT.
IT'S THE SAME STRATEGY THE NRA
USED AFTER CONGRESSWOMAN
GABRIELLE GIFFORDS WAS SHOT.
INSTEAD OF PUBLICLY ARGUING ITS
SIDE, THE NRA MOBILIZED,
ACCORDING TO THE CENTER FOR
RESPONSIVE POLITICS THE GUN
RIGHTS ORGANIZATION SPENT MORE
ON LOBBYING IN 2011 THAN IT EVER
HAD, $2.5 MILLION, AND IT
PROMOTED PERSONAL SAFETY THROUGH
GUN OWNERSHIP, LIKE IT DID
FOLLOWING BOB COSTAS' PASSIONATE
PLEA FOR GUN CONTROL AFTER JOVAN
BELCHER SHOT AND KILLED HIS
GIRLFRIEND AND THEN HIMSELF.
>> HE WOULDN'T HAVE SAID A THING
IF THIS WOMAN HAD SAVED HER LIFE
HAVING A FIREARM AVAILABLE FROM
JOVAN BELCHER.
>> Reporter: IT WASN'T LONG
BEFORE TALK ABOUT BELCHER, THE
NFL AND GUN CONTROL DIED DOWN.
AS FOR GUN CONTROL LEGISLATION
PASSED AFTER GABBY GIFFORDS WAS
SHOT?
ZERO.
OF COURSE I MEANT TO SAY SANDY
HOOK, I APOLOGIZE BUT KEEP IN
MIND THE NRA IS POWERFUL NOT
JUST BECAUSE IT'S WELL FUNDED
BUT BECAUSE IT HAS 4 MILLION
MEMBERS, THAT'S LIKE 4 MILLION
VOTES IN YOUR POCKET AND IT
REMAINS TO BE SEEN IF LAWMAKERS
HAVE THE POLITICAL WILL IN THE
FACE OF ALL THOSE PHOTOS.
>> THE POLLS ARE SHIFTING.
IT WILL BE INTERESTING TO SEE IF
THERE IS POLITICAL WILL THAT
COMES OUT OF THAT, CAROL.
THE NEW POLLS AFTER THE
SHOOTINGS AT SANDY HOOK SHOW
MORE AMERICANS ARE IN FAVOR OF
STRICTER GUN LAWS.
57% OF AMERICANS FAVOR STRONGER
GUN LAWS AND 30% SAY THEY SHOULD
BE LEFT WHERE THEY ARE.
50% OF THE RESPONDENTS SAY
STRICTER GUN LAWS WOULD NOT HAVE
HELPED PREVENT HORRIBLE EVENTS
THAT HAPPENED AT SANDY HOOK ON
FRIDAY.
>>> TEXAS GOVERNOR RICK PERRY
WHO IS A LONG TIME SUPPORTER OF
GUN RIGHTS IS SPEAKING OUT AFTER
THE TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN AT A TEA
PARTY MEETING.
HE SAID TEXANS SHOULD BE ALLOWED
TO CARRY GUNS ANYWHERE INCLUDING
SCHOOLS.
LISTEN.
>> IN THE STATE OF TEXAS, WITH
OUR CONCEALED HANDGUN LICENSE IF
YOU GO THROUGH THE PROCESS AND
YOU HAVE BEEN DUALLY
BACKGROUNDED AND TRAINED AND YOU
ARE A CONCEALED HANDGUN LICENSED
CARRYING INDIVIDUAL, YOU SHOULD
BE ABLE TO CARRY YOUR HANDGUN
ANYWHERE IN THIS STATE.
>> Reporter: GOVERNOR PERRY ALSO
SAID SOME TEXAS SCHOOL DISTRICTS
ALREADY ALLOW ARMED SCHOOL
PERSONNEL AND THE AUDIENCE
APPLAUDED HIM LOUDLY.
WEST VIRGINIA SENATOR JOE
MANCHIN HAS ALWAYS BEEN A STRONG
ADVOCATE FOR GUN RIGHTS BUT WHEN
I SPOKE TO HIM EARLIER ON
"STARTING POINT" HE SAID IT'S
TIME TO SIT DOWN AND LOOK FOR A
NEW APPROACH.
WE'RE BACK IN JUST A MOMENT.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH A SELECT TERRAIN DIAL
THAT ADJUSTS THE JEEP
GRAND CHEROKEE'S PERFORMANCE
FOR SPECIFIC WEATHER
AND ROAD CONDITIONS...
♪
...EVEN HEAVY SNOWSTORMS...
WON'T KEEP YOU
FROM GETTING TO WORK.
OUR APOLOGIES.
♪
>>> IT WAS JUST A COUPLE MINUTES
AGO I TOLD YOU THERE WERE BRIGHT
SPOTS IN THE NEGOTIATIONS TO
AVOID THAT FISCAL CLIFF WE'VE
ALL BEEN TALKING ABOUT FOR SO
LONG, THAT PRESIDENT OBAMA WAS
WILLING TO COMPROMISE ON WHO WAS
TAXED MORE AND HOW MUCH MONEY
THEY MADE BUT APPARENTLY THERE'S
BEEN A SETBACK.
LET'S GO TO DANA BASH OUR
CONGRESSIONAL CORRESPONDENT.
YOU HAVE THE BREAKING DETAILS.
WHAT ARE THEY?
>> Reporter: I'M NOT SURE IF
THIS IS A SETBACK OR SIGNIFICANT
CHANGE IN NEGOTIATING TACTICS.
THE HOUSE SPEAKER IS IN THE ROOM
NEXT TO ME SPEAKING WITH HIS
REPUBLICAN RANK AND FILE AND
WHAT HE IS TELLING THEM IS THAT
SIGNIFICANT MOVE THAT
REPUBLICANS POLITICALLY DO NOT
WANT TO BE IN A POSITION WHERE
THEY ARE SITTING HERE JANUARY
1st AND THE WHOLE COUNTRY'S
TAXES ARE GOING TO GO UP AND
CLEARLY THEY KNOW POLITICALLY
THEY'LL GET THE BLAME FOR IT SO
THEY'LL MOVE ON A SEPARATE TRACK
TO MAKE SURE PEOPLE THAT MAKE UP
TO $1 MILLION WON'T SEE AN
INCREASE IN TAX RATES ON JANUARY
1st.
>> GOTCHA.
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT ELSE COULD WE DO?
WE'LL SEE WHAT HAPPENS.
DANA BASH REPORTING LIVE.
>> Reporter: THE SPEAKER WILL
SPEAK TO REPORTERS AT 10:00 SO
WE'LL HAVE MORE THEN.
>> DANA BASH THANK YOU SO MUCH.
WE'LL TAKE A QUICK BREAK AND BE
BACK WITH MUCH MORE AFTER THIS.
HOW YOU DOING TODAY?
I'M GOOD THANKS.
HOW ARE YOU?
I'M GOOD.
[ Gordon ] BUT FOR OTHERS,
IT'S ALL THEY CAN AFFORD.
EVERY DAY NEARLY NINE MILLION
OLDER AMERICANS
DON'T HAVE ENOUGH TO EAT.
ANYTHING ELSE?
NO, NOT TODAY.
JOIN ME, AARP,
AND AARP FOUNDATION
IN THE DRIVE TO END HUNGER
BY VISITING
DRIVETOENDHUNGER.ORG.
>>> GOOD MORNING, THANK YOU SO
MUCH FOR BEING WITH US.
I'M CAROL COSTELLO IN ATLANTA,
SOLEDAD O'BRIEN IS IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, SHE JOINS US LIVE.
GOOD MORNING.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING TO
YOU, CAROL.
HERE IS THE LATEST TODAY.
CLASSES RESUME FOR MOST OF THE
KIDS IN THIS COMMUNITY, MANY OF
THEM STILL WRESTLING WITH SO
MUCH HEARTBREAK.
ALL THE NEWTOWN SCHOOLS EXCEPT
FOR SANDY HOOK ELEMENTER HAVE
SCHOOL ARE REOPENING TODAY.
THE GRIEF AND FEARS OF RETURNING
STUDENTS ARE GOING TO BE A HUGE
CONCERN NO DOUBT, ADDITIONAL
COUNSELORS AND POLICE OFFICERS
WILL BE AT EVERY SCHOOL.
TODAY THE GRANDMOTHER OF
CHARLOTTE BACON SAYS THE
6-YEAR-OLD WAS A BUNDLE OF
ENERGY, SHE IS LAID TO REST
TODAY AND 6-YEAR-OLD JESS ISICA
REKOS LIVED AND BREATHED HORSES.
SHE WAS EXPECTING A PAIR OF
COWGIRL BOOTS FOR CHRISTMAS.
YOU CAN SEE SENATOR MANCHIN IN
AN AD CALLED DEAD AIM.
IN THE AFTERMATH OF SANDY HOOK,
HE'S HAD A CHANGE OF HEART.
I SPOKE WITH HIM EARLIER AND
HERE'S WHAT HE TOLD ME.
>> I KNOW EVERYBODY IS GRIEVING
AS HARD AS WE'RE GRIEVING IN
WEST VIRGINIA AS HARD AS I'M
GRIEVING.
I REALLY CAN'T IMAGINE.
I DON'T HAVE WORDS FOR THAT, MY
SYMPATHIES FOR THEM.
WITH THAT BEING SAID WE HAVEN'T
HOPEFULLY BECOME A SOCIETY OR
BECOME EVEN A GOVERNING BODY
THAT WE CAN'T SIT DOWN AND TALK.
WE CAN'T LAY EVERYTHING ON THE
TABLE TO FIND OUT HOW DO WE MOVE
FORWARD WHEN WE KNOW WE HAVE
CHALLENGES AND YOU KNOW, I'M A
BIG PROPONENT OF COLIN POWELL'S
FIVE PROMISES TO CHILDREN.
THE SECOND PROMISE IS EVERY
CHILD SHOULD HAVE A SAFE PLACE
IN THEIR LIFE.
SOMETIMES IT'S NOT ALWAYS THE
HOME.
MORE THAN OFTEN IT'S THE SCHOOL
AND IT LOOKS LIKE THAT'S EVEN
BEEN TAKEN AWAY, SO IT IS TIME
TO SET DOWN.
IT'S TIME TO LOOK AT A
RESPONSIBLE, REASONABLE
APPROACH.
MENTAL ILLNESS, A CULTURE OF
VIOLENCE, SOMETIMES IT'S
ACCEPTED, EVEN GLORIFIED AND
THEN CERTAIN MILITARY STYLE
WEAPONS THAT REALLY AS A HUNTER
MYSELF, A PROUD DEFENDER OF THE
SECOND AMENDMENT, AS A PROUD
MEMBER OF THE NRA, WE SHOULD
QUESTION AND LOOK AND SEE IF
THERE'S A BETTER WAY TO DO THIS.
>> WOULD YOU THEN SUPPORT
LEGISLATION THAT WOULD BAN
ASSAULT WEAPONS?
WOULD YOU SUPPORT LEGISLATION
THAT WOULD GET RID OF
HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINES?
>> SOLEDAD, THAT ALL HAS TO COME
TO THE TABLE.
IF IT'S A POSSIBLY, REASONABLE
MANNER, I WOULD THINK THAT THE
MAJORITY OF AMERICANS WOULD
SUPPORT A REASONABLE APPROACH TO
THAT.
I'VE BEEN HUNTING ALL MY LIFE.
I'VE NEVER HAD MULTIPLE ROUNDS
OF CLIPS OF TEN OR MORE.
IT'S NOT NEEDED.
I'VE NEVER GONE WITH A
MILITARY-STYLE ASSAULT RIFLE
HUNTING.
IT'S NOT NEEDED.
SO WE NEED TO QUESTION THAT AND
WE NEED TO BRING THE NRA IN.
THESE ARE ALL GOOD PEOPLE.
THEY HAVE CHILDREN AND
GRANDCHILDREN.
THEY'RE HURTING, TOO.
THEY'RE GRIEVING.
SO YOU CAN'T VILLAINIZE, WE
WON'T MOVE FORWARD.
WE'LL BE IN A STALEMATE AGAIN
AND THAT'S NOT WHAT WE DESIRE.
>> DO YOU WORRY ABOUT POLITICAL
BACKLASH?
YOU SAID YOU'RE A PROUD MEMBER
OF THE NRA AS YOU KNOW THEY
OFTEN FUND CANDIDATES AND WORK
TO OVERTHROW FRANKLY CANDIDATES
WHO DON'T SUPPORT THE SAME KINDS
OF BELIEFS AND LEGISLATION THEY
SUPPORT.
DO YOU WORRY ABOUT BACKLASH FROM
YOUR CONSTITUENTS?
>> I COME FROM THE GREAT STATE
OF WEST VIRGINIA, THE MOST
WONDERFUL PEOPLE AND WE SIT DOWN
AND COME TO CONCLUSIONS WITH THE
FACTS.
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE ASKING FOR.
THERE'S ALWAYS GOING TO BE
MOVEMENT OR POLITICAL BACKLASH
ON ANYTHING AND EVERYTHING.
THE EASIEST VOTE TO TAKE IN
WASHINGTON IS A NO VOTE.
VOTE FOR NOTHING.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO EXPLAIN.
IF YOU'RE WILLING TO MOVE
FORWARD AND FOR THE SAKE OF OUR
CHILDREN, SOLEDAD, WE HAD 20
BEAUTIFUL BABIES THAT WERE
SLAUGHTERED.
THAT CANNOT BE TOLERATED IN
AMERICA.
>> JOE MANCHIN SAYS SITTING DOWN
AT THE TABLE, CAROL, IS THE
FIRST STEP TO COMING TO SOME
MEANINGFUL DIALOGUE ABOUT WHAT
CHANGES TO BE HAPPENED
CONSIDERED TO BE REASONABLE ON
BOTH SIDES OF THE ISSUE.
>> EVEN IN THIS CLIMATE, THAT'S
EASIER SAID THAN DONE.
THANKS, SOLEDAD.
>>> NOW IS YOUR CHANCE TO TALK
ABOUT ONE OF THE BIG STORIES OF
THE DAY, THE QUESTION IS THIS.
WHAT DOES OWNING A GUN REPRESENT
TO YOU?
THERE IS ONE INDUSTRY THAT IS
RECESSION PROOF, THE GUN
INDUSTRY.
AMERICANS SPEND ABOUT $3.5
BILLION EVERY YEAR ON GUNS.
EVEN IN THE DAYS AFTER 20 FIRST
GRADERS WERE SHOT MULTIPLE TIMES
GUN STORES WERE JAMMED IN CASE
WASHINGTON DECIDES TO CLAMP DOWN
ON GUNS.
>> THEY'RE GOING TO DO
SOMETHING, THAT'S OBVIOUS, AND
PEOPLE WANT TO GET STUFF BEFORE
A BAN ON WHATEVER COMES IN,
PROBABLY MAGAZINES, PEOPLE GET
SCARED.
>> CRITICS SAY AMERICA'S
ENORMOUS APPETITE FOR GUNS IS
LARGELY FUELED BY THE NATIONAL
RIFLE ASSOCIATION.
IT'S EASY TO SEE WHY.
THE IN, RA IS A MASTER WHEN IT
COMES TO PSYCHOLOGY.
LISTEN TO NRA EXECUTIVE VICE
PRESIDENT WAYNE LAPIERRE FROM
EARLIER THIS YEAR.
>> IF PRESIDENT OBAMA GETS ONE
MORE TERM IT WILL BREAK THE BACK
OF THE SECOND AMENDMENT IN THIS
COUNTRY.
THIS IS THE MOST DANGEROUS
ELECTION IN OUR LIFETIME, IF
YOU'RE A SUPPORTER OF THE SECOND
AMENDMENT.
>> REALLY?
MR. OBAMA DID NOT PUSH FOR A
SINGLE PIECE OF GUN CONTROL
LEGISLATION IN HIS FIRST TERM,
NO MATTER.
IN THE NRA'S WORLD OBAMA'S
SECOND TERM SPELLS DOOM OR MAYBE
WHAT HAPPENED AT SANDY HOOK
DOES.
DICK'S SPORTING GOODS IS NOT
SELLING THOSE TYPE OF WEAPONS.
THE LATE FAMOUS SAYING HE'D GIVE
YOU HIS GUN ONLY IF YOU PRIDE IT
OUT OF HIS HANDS.
>> FROM MY COLD, DEAD HANDS.
>> WHAT IS IT ABOUT GUNS THAT
CUTS TO THE CORE OF THE AMERICAN
PSYCHE, IS IT THE SECOND
AMENDMENT WHICH SAYS OUR RIGHT
TO BEAR ARMS SHALL NOT BE
INFRINGED OR IS IT AS FORMER NRA
LOBBYIST RICHARD FELDMAN SAYS
GUN OWNERS SEE THIS RELATIONSHIP
THROUGH THIS DEMOCRACY THROUGH
THE GUYS OF THE GUN ISSUE.
WHAT DOES OWNING A GUN REPRESENT
TO YOU?
FACEBOOK.COM/CAROLCNN, YOUR
RESPONSES LATER THIS HOUR.
>>> VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES, LET'S
TALK ABOUT THAT A LITTLE BIT,
SOME OF THE MOST POPULAR ON THE
MARKET.
EVERY TIME WE HEAR ABOUT A
SHOOTING, CONCERNS ARE BROUGHT
UP ABOUT THE VIOLENT VIDEO
GAMES.
SHOULD PARENTS BE WORRIED ABOUT
THE GAMES THEIR CHILDREN PLAY?
I NEED YOU.
I FEEL SO ALONE.
BUT YOU'RE NOT
ALONE.
I KNEW YOU'D COME.
LIKE I COULD STAY AWAY.
YOU KNOW I CAN'T DO THIS
WITHOUT YOU.
YOU'LL NEVER HAVE TO.
YOU'RE ALWAYS THERE
FOR ME.
SHH!
I'LL GET YOU
A RENTAL CAR.
I COULD ALSO USE
AN UMBRELLA.
FALL IN LOVE WITH
PROGRESSIVE'S CLAIMS SERVICE.
>>> SINCE THE SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT THERE'S BEEN A MAJOR
PUSH FOR GUN CONTROL IN THIS
COUNTRY, ONE DAY THE CALIFORNIA
SENATOR DIANNE FEINSTEIN PLANS
TO GO AFTER SIMILAR WEAPONS WHAT
THE SHOOTER USED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> I'M GOING TO DO AN ASSAULT
WEAPONS PIECE OF LEGISLATION AND
IT'S GOING TO BE STRONG AND IT'S
GOING TO BE DEFINITIVE AND IT'S
GOING TO BAN BY NAME AT LEAST
100 MILITARY-STYLE SEMIAUTOMATIC
ASSAULT WEAPONS AND IT'S GOING
TO BAN BIG CLIPS, DRUMS OR
STRIPS OF MORE THAN TEN BULLETS,
AND IT'S THIS PARTICULAR
CATEGORY OF WEAPON WHICH THE
BUSHMASTER IS.
IT'S A KILLER WEAPON.
YOU CAN FIND IT VERY QUICKLY,
VERY LITTLE RECOIL, VERY LITTLE
KICK AND IT'S VERY HIGH VELOCITY
AND IT DOESN'T BELONG ON THE
STREETS OF OUR CITY AND IT
DOESN'T BELONG IN A PLACE WHERE
A 20-YEAR-OLD LIKE THIS
PARTICULAR 20-YEAR-OLD COULD GET
A HOLD OF IT AND DO WHAT HE DID.
THIS MAKES ME VERY ANGRY.
>> THERE WAS A FEDERAL ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN, IT EXPIRED IN 2004.
>> THOSE WHO KNEW ADAM LANZA
SAID HE LOVED VIDEO GAMES.
HE WAS A MEMBER OF THE SCHOOL'S
TECH CLUB IN HIGH SCHOOL.
MEMBERS OF THE TECH CLUB PLAYED
THE COMPUTER VIDEO GAMES
INCLUDING THE ONE YOU'RE LOOKING
AT "STARCRAFT" YOU COMMAND
ARMIES TO DEFEAT YOUR OPPONENTS.
IS THERE A LINK BETWEEN VIOLENT
VIDEO GAMES AND AGGRESSIVE
BEHAVIOR?
CRAIG ANDERSON IS A PROFESSOR AT
IOWA STATE UNIVERSITY AND
DIRECTOR OF THE CENTER FOR THE
STUDY OF VIOLENCE AND JOINS US
FROM AMES, IOWA.
WELCOME, SIR.
>> THANK YOU, HAPPY TO BE HERE,
CAROL.
>> GLAD TO HAVE YOU HERE.
IN YOUR MIND IS THERE A
CONNECTION BETWEEN VIOLENT VIDEO
GAME AND VIOLENCE IN REAL LIFE?
>> YES, THERE IS.
EVERY MAJOR SCIENTIFIC SOCIETY
THAT HAS STUDIED THE QUESTION
HAS COME TO THE SAME ANSWER, THE
MAEAMERICAN MEDICAL ASSOCIATION
THE AMERICAN PSYCHOLOGICAL
ASSOCIATION, THE NATIONAL
SOCIETY FOR RESEARCH AND
AGGRESSION HAVE COME TO THE SAME
CONCLUSION MEDIA VIOLENCE IS A
RISK FACTOR, IS A CAUSAL RISK
FACTOR FOR INCREASED AGGRESSIVE
BEHAVIOR INCLUDING VIOLENCE.
>> YEARS AGO BACK IN THE DAY WE
HEARD THE SAME THING ABOUT HEAVY
METAL MUSIC OR HARD ROCK MUSIC
WITH VIOLENT LYRICS AND THAT
KIND OF FELL BY THE WAYSIDE AND
NOBODY REALLY BELIEVES THAT, YOU
KNOW, LYRICS AND MUSIC SUCH AS
THAT TRANSLATES TO VIOLENT
BEHAVIOR IN THE REAL WORLD.
THAT'S TRUE.
THE SAME THING HAS HAPPENED TO
RESEARCH ON MOVIE VIOLENCE AND
TELEVISION VIOLENCE AND IN A
SENSE, THAT SPEAKS TO THE
STRENGTH OF THE INDUSTRIES MUCH
LIKE THE NRA, BUT THE MOVIE
INDUSTRY VIDEO GAME INDUSTRY AND
THEIR ABILITY TO KEEP THE
GENERAL PUBLIC CONFUSED ABOUT
WHAT THE RESEARCH SHOWS.
THE RESEARCH IS VERY CLEAR.
WE CONDUCTED, IT'S CALLED A META
ANALYSIS TYPE OF STUDY PUBLISHED
IN 2010 THAT LOOKED AT ALL OF
THE VIDEO GAME STUDIES THAT WE
COULD FIND AROUND THE WORLD,
INCLUDING A SUBSTANTIAL NUMBER
FROM JAPAN, AND REVIEWED THOSE
STUDIES AND COMBINED THEM USING
STATE-OF-THE-ART STATISTICAL
PROCEDURES AND CAME TO THE
CONCLUSION THAT EXPOSURE TO
VIDEO GAMES, VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES
CAN INCREASE AGGRESSIVE
BEHAVIOR.
>> SO PROFESSOR, WHAT EXACTLY,
HOW DOES IT AFFECT YOUR BRAIN?
DOES IT DESENSITIZE TO YOU
VIOLENCE?
WHAT DOES WATCHING OR PLAYING A
VIDEO GAME DO TO YOUR BRAIN TO
MAKE YOU MORE VIOLENT?
>> WELL, THERE ARE A NUMBER OF
PROCESSES GOING ON, SO IN THE
SHORT TERM, THAT IS RIGHT WHILE
ONE IS PLAYING THE GAME AND FOR
A BRIEF PERIOD AFTERWARDS,
AGGRESSIVE THOUGHTS ARE MORE
AVAILABLE.
IF A PROVOCATION OCCURS IN THAT
TIME PERIOD YOU'RE MORE TO SEE
IT AS A PROVOCATION AND
AGGRESSIVE SOLUTIONS COME TO
MIND.
LONGER TERM WE GET CHANGES IN
ATTITUDES TOWARDS USING
AGGRESSIVE SOLUTIONS, CHANGES IN
HOW ONE INTERPRETS SAY AMBIGUOUS
SITUATIONS, SO YOU GET BUMPED
INTO SAY A CHILD AND N A
LUNCHROOM.
THOSE WHO PLAY A LOT OF VIOLENT
VIDEO GAMES ARE MORE LIKELY TO
INTERPRET IN A BUMP AS
INTENTIONAL AND MORE LIKELY TO
RESPOND BY PUSHING BACK OR MAYBE
EVEN STARTING A FIGHT.
>> OKAY, SO THE FINAL QUESTION
AND THIS IS THE THING I THINK
CONFUSES PEOPLE.
MILLIONS OF PEOPLE PLAY GAMES
LIKE "WORLD OF WARCRAFT"
MILLIONS OF PEOPLE DO AND
MILLIONS DO NOT RESORT TO
VIOLENT BEHAVIOR IN THE REAL
WORLD SO HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN THE
DISCONNE
DISCONNECT.
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
THE IDEA IS THAT IT'S MUCH LIKE
SAY SMOKING AND LUNG CANCER.
SMOKING A CIGARETTE ISN'T GOING
TO CAUSE ALL CANCER.
SOME WHO DON'T SMOKE CAN GET
CANCER AND SOME WHO DO SMOKE
DON'T GET IT.
I LIKE TO POINT OUT TAKING A
NORMAL, HEALTHY, WELL-DEVELOPED
CHILD OR ADOLESCENT AND YOU
KNOW, IF THEY START PLAYING
VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES, THAT'S NOT
GOING TO TURN THEM INTO A SCHOOL
SHOOTER, MAINLY BECAUSE EXTREME
ACTS OF VIOLENCE ALWAYS REQUIRE
MULTIPLE RISK FACTORS TO BE
PRESENT.
AND MEDIA VIOLENCE IS ONLY ONE
OF MANY RISK FACTORS OUT THERE
FOR EXTREME KINDS OF AGGRESSION
AND VIOLENCE.
>> PROFESSOR CRAIG ANDERSON,
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR BEING WITH
US THIS MORNING.
>> YOU'RE WELCOME.
>>> WE'RE BACK IN A MINUTE WITH
A CHECK OF OUR TOP STORIES.
[ Woman ] Ring. Ring.
Progresso.
In what world do potatoes,
bacon and cheese
add up to 100 calories?
Your world.
♪
[ whispers ]
Real bacon...
Creamy cheese...
100 calories...
[ Chef ] Ma'am
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
>>> WE'LL TAKE YOU BACK TO
NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT IN JUST A
MINUTE.
THREE MONTHS AFTER THE DEADLY
ATTACK IN LIBYA CONGRESS
RECEIVES THE REPORT TODAY.
THE U.S. AMBASSADOR TO LIBYA
CHRIS STEVENS AND THREE OTHERS
WERE KILLED IN AN ATTACK ON
SEPTEMBER 11.
>>> ADVERTISERS REPORTING THEY
MAY HAVE TO WORK ON CHRISTMAS
DAY BOPS SANTA WANTS A BIG MAC
ON CHRISTMAS DAY.
IT CITES A MEMO URGING
FRANCHISEES TO OPEN TO HELP
BOOST SALES.
>>> RG 3 HAS SET A RECORD OFF
THE FEED.
ESPN.COM REPORTS THE RG 3 JERSEY
HAS SOLD MORE THAN ANY OTHER
PLAYERS IN A SINGLE SEASON SINCE
THE NFL STARTED KEEPING TRACK.
>>> HOLLYWOOD LEGEND MARTIN
SCORSESE WILL PRODUCE A
DOCUMENTARY ON BILL CLINTON.
CLINTON IS SAID TO BE
COOPERATING FULLY WITH THE
PROJECT.
>>> LET'S TAKE YOU BACK TO
NEWTOWN AND SOLEDAD.
>> I AM NOT SURPRISED HE IS
COOPERATING.
>> Reporter: HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT THE DAYS HAVE
CLEARED UP.
WE WERE IN A DOWN POUR WHICH
SOME PEOPLE WERE TALKING ABOUT
THE TOWN CRYING BECAUSE THE
WEATHER WAS SO BAD.
THE TOWN IS TRYING TO MAKE SENSE
OF THIS TERRIBLE TRAGEDY.
INVESTIGATORS TRYING TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE SHOOTER, ADAM
LANZA, ONE OF THOSE WHO MIGHT BE
ABLE TO OFFER INSIGHT IS ADAM
DIAZ WHO SPOKECLUSIVELY TO SUSAN
CANDIOTTI.
WE WILL HEAR FROM HIM THIS
MORNING.
ALSO AHEAD IN THE NEXT HOUR KIDS
IN EVERY SCHOOL HERE IN NEWTOWN
EXCEPT FOR SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
ARE BACK TO SCHOOL TODAY AND ON
HAND AT EVER SCHOOL IS GRIEF
COUNSELORS.
WE'LL UPDATE YOU ON WHAT IS
HAPPENING THERE.
I SPOKE WITH STEVE PERRY THE
PRINCIPAL OF CAPITAL SCHOOL AT
HARTFORD, CONNECTICUT.
WE WILL TALK TO HIM ABOUT WHAT
HE WOULD DO AT HIS SCHOOL.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN IT COMES TO
THE FINANCIAL OBSTACLES
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAND.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
>>> TALK BACK QUESTION FOR YOU
TODAY.
WHAT DOES OWNING A GUN MEAN TO
YOU?
THIS IS FROM CRYSTALAL.
A GUN MEANS PROTECTION FOR ME.
THIS IS FROM LISZA.
CONTROL OF MY OWN SAFETY.
MY ABILITY TO MAKE MY OWN
DECISIONS AND UNDERSTANDING OF
PERSONAL ACCOUNTABILITY, MINE
AND THE CRIMINALS.
THIS ONE FROM SHELLY NO ONE HAS
THE RIGHT TO OWN A GUN THAT CAN
KILL 20 CHILDREN IN A MINUTE AND
A HALF.
HAD MRS. LANZA SECURED HER
WEAPONS WE MIGHT NOT HAVE HAD SO
MUCH CARNAGE.
KEEP THE CONVERSATION GOING.
MORE OF YOUR RESPONSES IN THE
NEXT HOUR OF "NEWSROOM."
UP HIGH!
OK. DON'T YOU HAVE
ANY USEFULL APPS ON THAT THING?
WHO DO YOU THINK I AM,
Quicken Loans?
♪
AT Quicken Loans,
OUR AMAZINGLY USEFUL
MORTGAGE CALCULATOR APP
ALLOWS YOU TO QUICKLY CALCULATE
YOUR MORTGAGE PAYMENT
BASED ON TODAY'S INCREDIBLY LOW
INTEREST RATES...
RIGHT FROM YOUR IPHONE
OR ANDROID SMARTPHONE.
ONE MORE WAY Quicken Loans
IS ENGINEERED TO AMAZE.
♪
How advanced is the
new Ford Fusion?
Well...it has outstanding
performance and handling...
...and it offers a plug-in
hybrid
that gets a projected 100 MPGe.
Of course, there's still
one thing it can't do.
Introducing the entirely
new Ford Fusion.
It's an entirely new idea of
what a car can be.
but with ADVAIR,
I'm breathing better.
So now I can be in
the scene.
ADVAIR is
clinically proven to help
significantly improve
lung function.
Unlike most COPD medications,
ADVAIR contains both an
anti-inflammatory
and a
long-acting bronchodilator
working together to help improve
your lung function all day.
ADVAIR won't
replace fast-acting inhalers
for sudden symptoms
and should not be used more
than twice a day.
People with
COPD taking ADVAIR
may have a higher chance
of pneumonia.
ADVAIR may increase your
risk of osteoporosis
and some eye problems.
Tell your doctor
if you have a heart condition
or high blood pressure before
taking ADVAIR.
If you're still
having difficulty breathing,
ask your doctor if including
ADVAIR could help
improve your lung function.
Get your
first full
prescription
free
and save
on refills
at
ADVAIRcopd.com.
>>> JUST DAYS AFTER THAT DEADLY
SCHOOL SHOOTING AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL FELLOW
STUDENTS IN NEWTOWN ARE HEADING
BACK TO THE CLASSROOM.
IT IS NOT GOING TO BE EASY.
HOW DO YOU HELP THEM COPE?
PLUS AN EXCLUSIVE INTERVIEW WITH
A FORMER CLASSMATE OF ADAM LANZA
WHO EXPLAINS INFORMATION ABOUT
THE GUNMAN'S CHILDHOOD.
>> HE WAS A VERY INTELLIGENT
PERSON BUT THE WAY HE ACTED WITH
OTHER PEOPLE WAS WITHDRAWN AND
QUIET.
>>> AND LIES SPREAD ABOUT THE
SANDY HOOK CASE.
THEY SAY THEY WILL GO AFTER
SOCIAL MEDIA USERS WHO POST FAKE
POSTS.
"NEWSROOM" STARTS NOW.
>>> GOOD MORNING.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR BEING WITH
US.
I'M CAROL COSTELLO IN ATLANTA.
WE WILL CHECK IN WITH SOLEDAD
O'BRIEN IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THIS MORNING A SMALL CHECK
TOWARDS NORMALCY.
CLASSES RESUME FOR MOST KIDS IN
THE COMMUNITY STILL WRESTLING
WITH SO MUCH HEARTBREAK.
THE GRIEF AND FEARS OF THE
RETURNING STUDENTS WILL BE A
HUGE CONCERN.
ADDITIONAL COUNSELORS AND POLICE
OFFICERS WILL BE AT EVERY SINGLE
SCHOOL.
TODAY THE TOWN LAYS TO REST TWO
MORE OF ITS YOUNGEST VICTIMS.
THE GRANDMOTHER OF CHARLOTTE
BACON SAYS THE 6-YEAR-OLD WAS A
BUNDLE OF ENERGY WHO LOVED
DRESSES AND SCHOOL.
6-YEAR-OLD JESSICA REKOS LOVED
HORSES.
SHE WAS EXCITED ABOUT A PAIR OF
COW GIRL BOOTS SHE WAS EXPECTING
AT CHRISTMAS TIME.
BOTH OF THOSE GIRLS LAID TO REST
TODAY.
NOW LET'S HEAD BACK TO NEWTOWN.
>> Reporter: MORE TO TELL YOU
ABOUT THE GUNMAN WHILE THE
COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN IS TRYING
TO MAKE SENSE OF THE TRAGEDY.
INVESTIGATORS ARE TRYING TO
LEARN MORE ABOUT ADAM LANZA AND
ONE OF THOSE WHO MIGHT BE ABLE
TO OFFER A LITTLE BIT OF INSIGHT
IS ADAM DIAZ, A FORMER CLASSMATE
OF LANZA' WHO SPOKE WITH SUSAN
CANDIOTTI.
>> Reporter: AMONG THE STEADY
STREAM OF PEOPLE DRAWN TO THIS
MEMORIAL HONORING VICTIMS, A
FORMER SCHOOLMATE OF THE ALLEGED
KILLER.
>> BECAUSE YOU KNOW HE IS A VERY
BIG PART IN THIS EVENT.
I'M NOT REALLY SURE WHAT TO
THINK OF IT.
>> Reporter: SADLY, HE IS THE
REASON FOR IT.
>> YEAH.
>> Reporter: ALLEN DIAZ MAY HAVE
BEEN AS CLOSE AS ANYONE COULD
COME TO BEING A FRIEND OF ADAM
LANZA.
>> HE WAS A VERY INTELLIGENT
PERSON.
HE REALLY WAS.
THE WAY HE ACTED AROUND OTHER
PEOPLE WAS VERY WITHDRAWN AND
REALLY QUIET.
>> Reporter: A LITTLE DIFFERENT.
>> YEAH.
>> Reporter: THEY WERE IN THE
HIGH SCHOOL TECH CLUB TOGETHER
AND SPENT A LOT OF TIME ON
COMPUTERS.
ADAM HAD HIS OWN STYLE OF
DRESSING.
>> HE HAD THE STEREOTYPICAL NERD
LOOK.
KHAKI PANTS, BELT, TUCKED IN
SHIRT.
HE EVEN HAD A LITTLE COMPUTER
CASE INSTEAD OF A BACKPACK LIKE
EVERYONE ELSE.
HE HAD A POCKET PROTECTOR.
>> Reporter: HE DOESN'T KNOW
WHETHER LANZA WAS BULLIED.
HE KEPT TO HIMSELF.
>> WE ALL KIND OF NEW THAT HE
HAD PROBLEMS SOCIALLY.
AND WE KIND OF HAD A FEELING
THAT THERE MIGHT HAVE BEEN
SOMETHING WRONG WITH HIM BUT
OBVIOUSLY WE NEVER ASKED.
>> Reporter: BACK THEN HIS
SCHOOLMATES' MOM INVITED ALL THE
FRIENDS TO THE HOUSE TO PLAY
VIDEO GAMES.
ONE WAS STAR CRAFT, KIND OF A
WAR GAMES IN SPACE.
ANOTHER WAS WAR CRAFT 3 WHERE AS
THE AD SAYS SURVIVAL IS A MATTER
OF STRATEGY.
>> WAR CRAFT 3 WAS REALLY FUN.
HE WAS REALLY INTO GAMES.
AS I RECALL HE PICKED UP ON STAR
CRAFT QUICKLY.
>> Reporter: WHEN LANZA LEFT
HIGH SCHOOL AND WAS HOME
SCHOOLED DIAZ LOST TOUCH BUT RAN
INTO ADAM MFS MOTHER.
>> I REMEMBER HER MENTIONING
THAT HE STARTED GOING TO THE
SHOOTING RANGE WITH HER.
I NEVER IMAGINED ADAM WANTED TO
EVER HOLD A GUN.
>> Reporter: WHY DO YOU SAY
THAT?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE BECAUSE LIKE IN MY MIND I
DON'T IMAGINE SHY QUIET PEOPLE
GOING TO A SHOOTING RANGE.
I NEVER REALLY CAN MAKE THAT
ASSOCIATION.
>> Reporter: INVESTIGATORS ARE
TRACKING HOW OFTEN LANZA HAD
BEEN TO GUN RANGES.
THEY DON'T KNOW HOW MANY SO FAR.
THEY HAVE PROVEN HE HAS BEEN TO
TARGET PRACTICE ABOUT SIX MONTHS
AGO AND FOR SEVERAL YEARS.
MOTHERER AND SON WENT AT LEAST
ONCE TOGETHER.
ALLEN'S OLDER SISTER WENT TO
SCHOOL WITH LANZA'S OLDER
BROTHER.
>> WHY HER?
SHE WAS JUST -- IT WAS A SHOCK.
SHE WAS ALWAYS A HAPPY PERSON.
>> Reporter: DO YOU THINK OF HIM
AS AN EVIL PERSON BECAUSE OF
WHAT HE DID?
>> AT ONE POINT HE WAS A GOOD
KID.
THE EVENTS THAT HE DID THAT DAY
MAY HAVE BEEN EVIL BUT BEFORE
THEN HE WAS JUST ANOTHER KID.
>> Reporter: UNTIL SOMETHING
MADE HIM SNAP.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI, CNN, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> Reporter: THE GRADE SCHOOL
SHOOTING HERE IN CONNECTICUT IS
THE DEADLIEST OF ITS KIND IN
U.S. HISTORY.
THE TRAGEDY IS FORCING SCHOOL
OFFICIALS TO ASK IF THEY ARE
DOING ENOUGH TO PROTECT
CHILDREN.
IS LISA SYLVESTOR IS IN
WASHINGTON, D.C. THIS MORNING.
>> I KNOW YOU KNOW THIS BUT THEY
SAY WHEN YOU BECOME A PARENT
THAT A LITTLE BIT OF YOUR HEART
LIVES OUTSIDE YOU BUT FOR MANY
PARENTS THIS TRAGEDY HIT UPON
THEIR WORST FEARS.
HOW DO YOU KEEP YOUR KIDS SAFE
WHEN THEY ARE AWAY FROM YOU AT
SCHOOL?
>> YOU TRY NOT TO THINK ABOUT IT
BUT IT IS DIFFICULT.
>> Reporter: GINA HAS A HARD
TIME HOLDING BACK THE TEARS.
>> IT IS HEARTBREAKING.
IT'S VERY DIFFICULT TO IMAGINE
AND I CAN'T IMAGINE BEING ONE OF
THOSE PARENTS.
>> Reporter: WHAT HAPPENED IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT COULD HAVE
HAPPENED IN ANY TOWN.
IT IS ONE OF THE QUIET FEARS
PARENTS HAVE THAT HAS NOW RISEN
TO THE SURFACE.
PAGE ANDERSON HAS A 6-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHTER.
>> MY DAUGHTER WAS TELLING ME
THAT THEY DID A DRILL LAST WEEK
SO I THINK THEY DO THEM ON A
REGULAR BASIS.
YOU CAN'T PREPARE FOR EVERY
EVENTUALLITY.
>> Reporter: SCHOOLS ARE
REVIEWING PROGRAMS.
HIGH SCHOOLS IN VIRGINIA HAVE
TRAINED POLICE OFFICERS ON
CAMPUS.
MIDDLE SCHOOLS AND ELEMENTARY
SCHOOLS REQUIRE ALL VISITORS TO
BE BUZZED AND SIGNED IN.
FOR THE SCHOOL SUPERINTENDENT
THIS IS ALL DEEPLY PERSONAL.
HE VISITED A KINDERGARTEN AND
FIRST GRADE CLASS TO OFFER ANY
NEEDED COMFORT AND REASSURANCE.
>> IT IS REALLY EMOTIONAL.
JUST GOING INTO THE CLASSROOMS
AND LOOKING AT THOSE WONDERFUL
CHILDREN, LOOKING AT THEIR FACES
AND REALIZED THEY ARE BUT FOR
THE GRACE OF GOD COULD BE OUR
KIDS HERE.
>> Reporter: THE SHOOTING IN
NEWTOWN IS OPENING UP A NEW
CONVERSATION.
HOW MUCH SECURITY AT SCHOOLS IS
ENOUGH?
SHOULD THERE BE ARMED GUARDST AT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS AND
PRESCHOOLS, METAL DETECTORS?
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGISTS SAY THERE
HAS TO BE A BALANCE.
>> WE KNOW THAT HAVING METAL
DETECTORS AND SECURITY PEOPLE
WITH GUNS STANDING OUT OF THE
SCHOOL NOT ONLY WOULD MOST
PARENTS NOT WANT TO DROP OFF
THEIR 6-YEAR-OLD AT SCHOOL LIKE
THAT BUT THAT DOESN'T DECREASE
VIOLENCE AND IT CAN DECREASE THE
PERCEIVED SENSE OF SAFETY.
>> Reporter: SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGISTS SAY KIDS NEED A
GREATER SENSE OF SECURITY THAT
WHEN THEY GET ON THAT SCHOOL BUS
THEY WILL RETURN HOME.
SO SOME OF THE THINGS A SCHOOL
CAN DO, THE NATIONAL ASSOCIATION
OF SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGISTS SAYS
SCHOOLS SHOULD ESTABLISH A
CRISIS RESPONSE TEAM TO DEAL
WITH ANY EMERGENCIES.
THEY SHOULD ALSO COMMUNICATE
WITH PARENTS AND EXPLAIN WHAT
KIND OF STEPS ARE BEING DONE TO
KEEP THEIR CHILDREN SAFE AND
REVIEW ALL POLICIES AND HAVE
COUNSELORS AND PSYCHOLOGISTS ON
HAND TO DEAL WITH ANY EMOTIONAL
NEEDS THAT CHILDREN MIGHT HAVE.
>> THIS IS AN OPPORTUNITY FOR
PEOPLE TO REVIEW ALL OF THE
THINGS THAT THEY DO ALREADY AND
WHAT THEY SHOULD BE DOING.
THANK YOU, LISA.
APPRECIATE IT.
LET'S GET RIGHT BACK TO CAROL
COSTELLO.
>> THANKS.
LET'S TALK A LITTLE POLITICS
NOW.
WE ARE AWAITING A NEWS
CONFERENCE FROM HOUSE SPEAKER
JOHN BOEHNER.
WE THOUGHT THERE WAS A BRIGHT
SPOT ON THE BRINK OF THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
JUST WHEN WE THOUGHT THAT THE
SPIRIT OF COMPROMISE WAS IN THE
AIR MR. BOEHNER DECIDED TO THROW
THE PRESS CONFERENCE THAT IS
ABOUT TO BEGIN.
SUPPOSEDLY MR. BOEHNER IS GOING
TO INTRODUCE A PLAN B BECAUSE
NEGOTIATIONS AREN'T MOVING ALONG
FAST ENOUGH.
LET'S HEAD TO THE WHITE HOUSE
BECAUSE DAN LOTHIAN IS COVERING
THE STORY, TOO.
JUST AN HOUR AGO I TALKED TO YOU
ABOUT THIS BRIGHT SPOT AND
COMPROMISE IN THE AIR.
WHAT THE HECK HAPPENED?
>> IT IS LIKE A SEE SAW GOING UP
AND DOWN.
FROM SPEAKER BOEHNER'S OFFICE WE
ARE TOLD THAT THERE IS THIS
SENSE OF URGENCY WITH THE CLOCK
WINDING DOWN TO THE BIG
DEADLINE.
THERE IS CONCERN THAT THERE
HASN'T BEEN AN AGREEMENT.
AND SO THE SPEAKER WANTS TO OPEN
UP THE SECOND TRACK OR THE PLAN
B AS YOU HAVE JUST MENTIONED.
AND MY COLLEAGUE HEARING FROM A
GOP SOURCE THAT THAT PLAN B
WOULD BE SOME KIND OF
LEGISLATION TO EXTEND THOSE BUSH
ERA TAX CUTS FOR THOSE MAKING UP
TO $1 MILLION.
THAT IS THE PLAN B RIGHT NOW.
AS FOR REACTION FROM THE WHITE
HOUSE I DID REACH OUT TO A
NUMBER OF FOLKS HERE I WAS SOLD
THAT THE PRESIDENT DID SPEAK
WITH SPEAKER BOEHNER LAST NIGHT
BY PHONE.
HE WAS INFORMED ABOUT THE PLAN B
BUT WAS NOT GIVING ANY DETAILS
ABOUT WHAT THAT PLAN B WOULD BE.
OF COURSE, THIS COMES ON THE
HEELS OF SOME GREAT OPTIMISM I
THINK WHEN THE PRESIDENT
OVERNIGHT BACKED OFF WHAT HE HAD
HELD FOR SO LONG ON THE CAMPAIGN
TRAIL THAT INSISTING THAT THE
BUSH ERA TAX CUTS HAD TO EXPIRE
FOR THOSE MAKING MORE THAN
$250,000.
THE PRESIDENT NOW RAISING THAT
UP TO $400,000.
THAT IS VERY DRAMATIC BECAUSE
ALL ALONG THIS WHITE HOUSE HAD
INSISTED THAT THERE WOULD BE NO
DEAL IF THOSE TAXES WERE
EXTENDED FOR THOSE MAKING MORE
THAN  $250,000.
WE WILL AWAIT TO SEE.
I CAN TELL YOU IS THAT A SOURCE
HERE SAYING THE OFFER FROM THE
PRESIDENT WAS NOT THE FINAL
OFFER AND THAT WAS THE OFFER
MADE YESTERDAY.
IT WAS A 45-MINUTE MEETING.
INDICATIONS THAT IT IS NOT THE
FINALAL OFFER SO SOME SENSE THAT
THERE IS ROOM FOR COMPROMISE.
WE ARE GETTING UP AND DOWN WHERE
YOU GET A BIT OF OPTIMISM AND
THEN SOMETHING ELSE GETS THROWN
INTO THE MIX.
>> WE ARE GOING TO GO TO A
DIFFERENT PLACE ON CAPITOL HILL,
SPEAK TO DANA BASH.
JOHN BOEHNER IS BACK TO SPEAK.
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY -- WHAT IS
THIS PLAN B?
IS THIS A STEP FORWARD OR A STEP
BACKWARD?
>> Reporter: I THINK IT IS A
STEP SIDE WAYS BECAUSE HE IS
TELLING HIS RANK AND FILE THAT
HE IS GOING TO PREPARE THIS PLAN
B, THIS DIFFERENT TRACK WHICH
WILL -- I'M TOLD ACTUALLY THAT
THEY ARE TELLING LAWMAKERS THAT
THEY COULD HAVE THREE POTENTIAL
LEGISLATOR WAYS TO DO THIS AND
THEY ARE GOING TO TRY TO FIGURE
OUT THROUGHOUT THE DAY HOW TO
PUT IT FORWARD.
THE BIG PICTURE IS THAT THEY
UNDERSTAND THAT THEY WILL GET
THE BLAME, THEY MEANING
REPUBLICANS IF EVERYBODY'S TAXES
GO UP ON JANUARY 1.
THAT IS THE WAY THE POLLING
SHOWS AND THE WAY IT IS
POLITICLY FOR THEM.
THEY JUST DON'T HAVE A LOT OF
LEVERAGE.
THAT IS WHY THEY ARE POLITICLY
PREPARING FOR THAT TO MAKE SURE
THEY DON'T GET THE BLAME.
ALSO, THIS IS FOR SURE A
NEGOTIATING TACTIC.
IT IS A WAY FOR THE SPEAKER TO
KIND OF PUT THE PRESSURE ON THE
PRESIDENT TO GIVE HIM MORE OF
WHAT REPUBLICANS WANT AND MORE
IS GREATER SPENDING CUTS AND
FEWER TAX INCREASES.
THAT IS THE GIST OF WHAT HE IS
TELLING HIS PEOPLE.
I AM TOLD BY A NUMBER OF
REPUBLICAN LAWMAKERS THAT
SPEAKER WASN'T VERY SPECIFIC ON
WHERE THESE PRIVATE TALKS ARE
BETWEEN HIM AND THE PRESIDENT
EXCEPT THAT THEY DON'T HAVE A
DEAL.
WE ALSO HAVE INFORMATION THAT
WHAT THEY ARE TALKING ABOUT IS
POTENTIALLY PUTTING THIS ON THE
FLOOR AS EARLY AS THURSDAY.
SO IN TWO DAYS.
THIS IS SOMETHING THAT THEY ARE
GOING TO MOVE VERY FAST ON TO
TRY TO, AGAIN, AVOID TAKING THE
BLAME FOR TAX INCREASES
PARTICULARLY ON THOSE THAT MAKE
LESS THAN $1 MILLION A YEAR.
>> WHEN THE HOUSE SPEAKER BEGINS
SPEAKING WE WILL TAKE YOU BACK
TO CAPITOL HILL.
>>> NEW DEVELOPMENTS FOR AN
AMERICAN JOURNALIST AND HIS
PRODUCTION CREW.
FIVE DAYS AFTER THEIR CAPTURE
THEY ARE SAFELY OUT OF SYRIA.
THEY DISAPPEARED LAST THURSDAY
AFTER CROSSING INTO NORTHWESTERN
SYRIA FROM TURKEY.
THIS MORNING HE TOLD THE TODAY
SHOW THEY WERE NOT PHYSICALLY
TORTURED BUT WERE MENTALLY
TORTURED.
>> THEY TOOK US TO A SERIES OF
SAFEHOUSES AND INTERROGATION
PLACES AND THEY KEPT US BLIND
FOLDED, BOUND.
WE WEREN'T PHYSICALLY BEATEN
ORATORTURED.
THREATS OF BEING KILLED.
THEY MADE US CHOOSE WHICH ONE OF
US WOULD BE SHOT FIRST.
WHEN WE REFUSED THERE WERE MOCK
SHOOTINGS.
WHEN YOU WERE BLIND FOLDED AND
TOLD AND THEN THEY FIRE THE GUN
IN THE AIR IT CAN EBE VERY
TRAUMATIC EXPERIENCE.
>> I'LL SAY.
THEY SAY THEY WERE RELEASED
AFTER THE CAPTORS GOT INTO A
GUNFIGHT AT A CHECK POINT.
>>> STATE DEPARTMENT HAS BEEN
UNDER SCRUTINY FOR MONTHS.
NOW THEY WILL SHARE NEW FINDINGS
WITH CONGRESS AS EARLY AS TODAY
THEY WILL SHARE THE REPORT.
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON ORDERED THE REVIEW.
LAWMAKERS WILL BE GIVEN A
CLASSIFIED BRIEFING BEFORE
FORMAL HEARINGS THIS WEEK.
>>> IT WILL NOT BE EASY FOR
STUDENTS GOING BACK TO SCHOOL IN
CONNECTICUT.
THEIR SENSE OF SECURITY HAS BEEN
ABSOLUTELY SHATTERED FOLLOWING
THAT AWFUL SHOOTING.
WHAT DO YOU TELL KIDS RETURNING
TO SCHOOL?
HOW DO YOU MAKE THEM BELIEVE
THEY ARE SAFE?
Wooohooo....Hahaahahaha!
Oh...there you go.
I'm gonna stand
up to her!
No you're not.
I know.
You know Ronny folks who save
hundreds of dollars
switching to GEICO
sure are happy.
How happy are they Jimmy?
Happier than a witch in
a broom factory.
Get happy. Get GEICO.
Fifteen minutes could save you
fifteen percent or more.
OH, LET ME GUESS --OU SEE THIS?
MORE WASHINGTON GRIDLOCK.
NO, IT'S WORSE -- LOOK,
OUR TAXES ARE ABOUT TO GO UP.
NOT THE TAXES ON OUR
DIVIDENDS THOUGH, RIGHT?
THAT'S A BIG PART
OF OUR RETIREMENT.
OH, NO,
IT'S DIVIDENDS, TOO.
THE RATE ON OUR DIVIDENDS
WOULD MORE THAN DOUBLE.
BUT WE DEPEND ON OUR DIVIDENDS
TO HELP PAY OUR BILLS.
WE WORKED HARD TO SAVE.
WELL, THE PRESIDENT
AND CONGRESS HAVE GOT
TO WORK TOGETHER TO STOP
THIS DIVIDEND TAX HIKE.
BEFORE IT'S TOO LATE.
EXECUTOR OF EFFICIENCY.
YOU CAN SPOT AN AMATEUR
FROM A MILE AWAY...
WHILE GOING SHOELESS
AND METAL-FREE IN SECONDS.
AND YOU...RENT FROM National.
BECAUSE ONLY National
LETS YOU CHOOSE ANY CAR
IN THE AISLE...AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE A FULL-SIZE
OR ABOVE,
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
NOW THIS...WILL WORK.
[ Male Announcer ]
JUST LIKE YOU, BUSINESS PRO.
JUST LIKE YOU.
GO National.
GO LIKE A PRO.
>>> ON A BALANCED APPROACH THAT
AVERTS THE FISCAL CLIFF.
WHAT WE HAVE OFFERED MEETS THE
DEFINITION OF BALANCE BUT THE
PRESIDENT IS NOT THERE YET.
THE WHITE HOUSE OFFERED
YESTERDAY WAS ESSENTIALLY $1.3
TRILLION IN NEW REVENUES FOR
ONLY $850 BILLION IN NET
SPENDING REDUCTIONS.
THAT'S NOT BALANCED IN MY
OPINION.
SO AT THE SAME TIME THAT WE ARE
GOING TO CONTINUE TO TALK TO THE
PRESIDENT WE ARE GOING TO ALSO
MOVE PLAN B.
I THINK WE ALL KNOW THAT EVERY
INCOME TAX FILER IN AMERICA IS
GOING TO PAY HIGHER RATES COME
JANUARY 1 UNLESS CONGRESS ACTS
SO I BELIEVE IT IS IMPORTANT
THAT WE PROTECT AS MANY AMERICAN
TAXPAYERS AS WE CAN.
AND OUR PLAN B WOULD PROTECT
AMERICAN TAXPAYERS WHO MAKE $1
MILLION OR LESS AND HAVE ALL OF
THEIR CURRENT RATES EXTENDED.
I CONTINUE TO HAVE HOPE THAT WE
CAN REACH A BROADER AGREEMENT
WITH THE WHITE HOUSE THAT WOULD
REDUCE SPENDING AS WELL AS HAVE
REVENUES ON THE TABLE.
I THINK IT WOULD BE BETTER FOR
OUR COUNTRY.
BUT AT THIS POINT HAVING A
BACKUP PLAN TO MAKE SURE THAT AS
FEW AMERICAN TAXPAYERS ARE
EFFECTED BY THIS INCREASE AS
POSSIBLE MOVING DOWN THAT PATH
IS THE RIGHT COURSE OF ACTION
FOR US.
>> GOOD MORNING.
FIRST I WOULD LIKE TO SAY THAT I
THINK ALL OF OUR HEARTS AND
PRAYERS ARE WITH THE FAMILIES IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
AS A FATHER I CANNOT EVEN
IMAGINE THE UTTER HORROR THAT
THOSE FAMILIES ARE GOING THROUGH
RIGHT NOW GRIEVING THE LOSS OF
THEIR CHILDREN AND THEIR LOVED
ONES.
AS FAR AS THE FISCAL CLIFF IS
CONCERNED AS THE SPEAKER HAS
SAID WE REMAIN COMMITTED TO
TRYING TO MINIMIZE THE IMPACT ON
HARD WORKING FAMILIES AND SMALL
BUSINESSES IN THIS COUNTRY AS
FAR AS TAX INCREASES ARE
CONCERNED.
WE LOOK TO FIND THE ANSWER TO
SOLVE THE PROBLEM ON THE
SPENDING ISSUE HERE IN
WASHINGTON.
THE PRESIDENT IS NOT YET THERE.
HE HAS NOT COME TO WHERE HE
NEEDS TO BE IN ORDER FOR US TO
PUSH THROUGH A BILL THAT REALLY
DOES BEGIN TO ADDRESS THE
PROBLEM.
AS THE SPEAKER SAID THAT IS WHY
WE ARE NOW DISCUSSING AN
ALTERNATIVE PLAN IF THE
PRESIDENT AND THE WHITE HOUSE
CANNOT COME OUR WAY.
THANK YOU.
>> WELL, AS THE SPEAKER AND THE
LEADER SAID, WE HAVE BEEN TRYING
TO MAKE SURE WE DO NOT GO OFF
THIS FISCAL CLIFF.
AT THE SAME TIME PUT AMERICA ON
A DIFFERENT PATH, ONE FOR JOB
CREATION AND ONE THAT TAKES CARE
OF OUR SPENDING.
I THINK MANY TIMES THE SPEAKER
FELT HE WAS NEGOTIATING WITH
HIMSELF AFTER PLAN AFTER PLAN
WHERE THE PRESIDENT STAYED
SILENT.
THOSE THREE WEEKS RIGHT AFTER
THE ELECTION WHEN THE FIRST IDEA
WAS SENT ACROSS TO THE PRESIDENT
FROM THE SPEAKER WE HEARD
NOTHING BUT SILENCE.
TODAY WE WILL HAVE TO GO TO PLAN
B.
BECAUSE WE WANT TO MAKE SURE WE
DO NOT GO OFF THE CLIFF AND WE
WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT WE KEEP
AN ECONOMY WHERE JOBS CAN BE
CREATED.
BUT THE THING WE HAVE TO
REMEMBER IS WHERE WE ARE IN THE
SITUATION.
WE ARE TWO MONTHS INTO A NEW
FISCAL YEAR.
YOU SHOULD ALWAYS LOOK AT THE
NUMBERS BECAUSE IT CAN TELL YOU
WHERE YOU ARE.
IN THOSE TWO MONTHS WE ARE $292
BILLION IN DEBT.
WHEN YOU READ THE NUMBERS THERE
IS POSITIVE NEWS.
REVENUES ARE UP BY 10%.
$30 BILLION.
THAT IS 1 BILLION LESS THAN YOU
GET IF YOU JUST RAISE THE TOP
TWO RATES FOR THE FIRST YEAR.
BUT THE SAD REALITY IS SPENDING
IS UP 16%, $87 BILLION.
THAT IS WHERE THE PROBLEM LIES.
THAT IS WHERE THE PRESIDENT HAS
TO START TALKING ABOUT AND THAT
IS WHAT WE WANT TO SOLVE IN THE
LONG RUN, AN AMERICA FOR THE
CHILDREN AND A FUTURE THAT WE
CAN BUILD AND ONE THAT CAN
CREATE JOBS.
>>> THE CLOCK CONTINUES TO TICK
AND WE ARE JUST DAYS NOW FROM
THE END OF THE YEAR.
AND I THINK THAT THE BEST
CHRISTMAS GIFT THAT WE CAN GIVE
AMERICA IS AN AGREEMENT, AN
AGREEMENT THAT GIVES CERTAINTY
TO OUR HARD WORKING MIDDLE CLASS
FAMILIES AS TO WHAT THEIR TAX
RATES ARE GOING TO BE, THE SMALL
BUSINESS OWNERS SO THEY CAN HIRE
AND PURSUE THAT INNOVATION AND
THAT PROVES TO THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE THAT WE CAN LEAD AND GET
OUR JOB DONE.
THAT IS THE BEST CHRISTMAS GIFT
AND I AM CONFIDENT THAT WE CAN
GET IT DONE.
THIS IS OUR MOMENT.
THIS IS OUR MOMENT TO DO WHAT IS
GOOD AND RIGHT FOR AMERICA.
AND NOW WE ASK THE PRESIDENT TO
JOIN US IN THAT EFFORT.
>>> IN A NUT SHELL REPUBLICANS
SAY JUST IN CASE THE PRESIDENT
AND REPUBLICANS CAN'T COME TO AN
AGREEMENT TO AVOID THE FISCAL
CLIFF REPUBLICANS WILL INTRODUCE
A BILL IN THE HOUSE THAT WOULD
KEEP THOSE BUSH TAX CUTS IN
PLACE FOR PEOPLE MAKING UP TO $1
MILLION PER YEAR.
SO WHAT IS THE WHITE HOUSE'S
RESPONSE?
LET'S CHECK IN WITH DAN LOTHIAN.
ANY WORD?
>> Reporter: WE ARE STILL
WAITING FOR OFFICIAL RESPONSE
BUT SOURCES CLOSE IN THE
NEGOTIATION BELIEVE THAT THIS
BROADER AGREEMENT IS THE WAY TO
GO.
I SHOULD POINT OUT THAT WHILE
SPEAKER BOEHNER IS PUSHING THIS
SECOND OPTION OR THIS PLAN B HE
STILL WANTS TO MOVE FORWARD WITH
NEGOTIATIONS FOR THE BROADER
AGREEMENT.
SO THIS IS BY NO MEANS MEANING
THEY HAVE CUT OFF ANY FURTHER
TALKS WITH THE WHITE HOUSE.
THEY STILL EXPECT THAT TO
HAPPEN.
BUT THIS IS SORT OF THE BACKUP
PLAN BECAUSE THAT DEADLINE IS
QUICKLY APPROACHING.
AS FOR THE BALANCE BETWEEN
SPENDING CUTS AND REVENUE, THIS
IS SOMETHING THAT THE WHITE
HOUSE BELIEVES THAT THEY HAVE
MET.
SPEAKER BOEHNER HAD BEEN PUSHING
NOW FOR QUITE SOME TIME SAYING
THAT IS A MUST AND THE WHITE
HOUSE IN THAT NEW PROPOSAL THAT
THE PRESIDENT PUT FORWARD
YESTERDAY OFFERING $1.2 TRILLION
IN SPENDING CUTS AND $1.2
TRILLION IN NEW REVENUE.
THEY BELIEVE THAT THEY HAVE THE
NUMBERS ON THIS END.
SPEAKER BOEHNER'S OFFICE --
>> DAN, I'M GOING TO INTERRUPT
YOU BECAUSE HOUSE SPEAKER
BOEHNER IS ANSWERING QUESTIONS.
>> THE PRESIDENT IS CALLING FOR
1$1.3 TRILLION IN REVENUE AND
ONLY WILLING TO PUT $850 BILLION
WORTH OF CUTS OVER TEN YEARS.
>> Reporter: WHAT TYPE OF EFFECT
HAS THE TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT
HAD ON THE FISCAL CLIFF TALKS?
IS THERE A REALIZATION THAT THE
COUNTRY, THE LAST THING THEY
WANT TO SEE IS A LONG DRAWN OUT
BATTLE DURING THIS TIME?
>> I THINK BOTH SIDES WOULD
AGREE TO THAT.
THIS IS A DIFFICULT TIME FOR
AMERICANS.
THAT IS WHY WE CONTINUE TO HAVE
CONVERSATIONS WITH THE WHITE
HOUSE.
I CONTINUE TO HAVE HOPE THAT WE
CAN REACH AN AGREEMENT.
IT'S NOT A TIME TO PUT AMERICANS
THROUGH MORE STRESS.
>> Reporter: WHAT WOULD PLAN B
MEAN FOR THE OTHER BIG ISSUES
THAT WOULD CAUSE A FISCAL CLIFF?
THE SEQUESTRATION AND THE CUTS
THAT WOULD HAPPEN AUTOMATICALLY?
UNEMPLOYMENT BENEFITS GOING
AWAY?
WOULD YOU INCORPORATE ANY OF
THAT INTO THIS PLAN B
LEGISLATION?
>> WE ARE GOING TO CONTINUE TO
LOOK AT HOW WE WOULD ADDRESS
THOSE ISSUES.
AS WE PUT THIS BILL TOGETHER WE
EXPECT TO BE ON THE FLOOR LATER
THIS WEEK.
DEALING WITH THE ISSUE OF THE
ALTERNATIVE MINIMUM TAX AND THE
DEATH TAX COULD LIKELY BE PART
OF THE BILL THAT WE WOULD BRING
TO THE FLOOR.
WE WOULD NOT DEAL WITH
SEQUESTRATION.
>> Reporter: HOW CLOSE WOULD YOU
SAY THE PRESIDENT'S PLAN IS?
WILL THERE BE AN AGREEMENT?
>> I HAVE MADE IT CLEAR TO THE
PRESIDENT THAT I WOULD PUT $1
TRILLION WORTH OF REVENUE ON THE
TABLE IF YOU ARE WILLING TO PUT
$1 TRILLION OF SPENDING
REDUCTIONS ON THE TABLE.
THAT AT THIS POINT WOULD BE MY
VERSION OF A BALANCED APPROACH
AS HE CALLED FOR.
LAST ONE.
>> Reporter: HOW ADAMANT ARE YOU
THAT THE MEDICARE ELIGIBILITY
WOULD BE A PART OF THIS?
>> THERE ARE A LOT OF ISSUES ON
THE TABLE.
THAT ISSUE HAS BEEN ON THE
TABLE, OFF THE TABLE AND BACK ON
THE TABLE.
IT'S AN ISSUE FOR DISCUSSION.
BUT I DON'T BELIEVE IT IS AN
ISSUE THAT HAS TO BE DEALT WITH
BETWEEN NOW AND THE END OF THE
YEAR.
IT IS AN ISSUE IF CONGRESS WERE
TO DO ENTITLEMENT REFORM AND TAX
REFORM AS WE ENVISION IF THERE
IS AN AGREEMENT.
THAT ISSUE WILL CERTAINLY BE
OPEN TO DEBATE IN THAT CONTEXT.
THANKS.
>> HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER.
WE ARE GOING TO TAKE A QUICK
BREAK.
WHEN WE COME BACK, WHAT DOES
OWNING A GUN REPRESENT TO YOU?
[ Male Announcer ]
RED LOBSTER'S CRABFEST
ENDS SOON.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OUR TENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
PROGRESSIVE DIRECT AND OTHER
CAR INSURANCE COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
CALL OR CLICK TODAY.
♪ HARK HOW THE BELLS,
SWEET SILVER BELLS ♪
♪ ALL SEEM TO SAY
THROW CARE AWAY ♪
♪ FROM EVERYWHERE,
FILLING THE AIR ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
CHEX PARTY MIX.
EASY 15-MINUTE
HOMEMADE RECIPES
YOU JUST POP IN A MICROWAVE.
LIKE CARAMEL CHOCOLATE
DRIZZLES.
HAPPIER HOLIDAYS.
CHEX PARTY MIX.
>>> NOW IS YOUR CHANCE TO TALK
BACK.
THE QUESTION THIS MORNING.
WHAT DOES OWNING A GUN REPRESENT
TO YOU?
THERE IS ONE INDUSTRY THAT IS
RECESSION PROOF, THE GUN
INDUSTRY.
AMERICANS SPEND ABOUT $1.3
BILLION A YEAR ON GUNS EVEN THE
DAYS AFTER 20 FIRST GRADERS WERE
SHOT MULTIPLE TIMES GUN STORES
WERE JAMMED IN CASE WASHINGTON
DECIDES TO CLAMP DOWN ON GUNS.
>> THEY ARE GOING TO DO
SOMETHING.
THAT IS OBVIOUS.
AND PEOPLE WANT TO GET STUFF
BEFORE A BAN ON WHATEVER COMES
IN, PROBABLY MAGAZINES.
PEOPLE GET SCARED.
>> CRITICS SAY AMERICA'S
ENORMOUS APPETITE FOR GUNS IS
LARGELY FUELLED BY THE NATIONAL
RIFLE ASSOCIATION.
THE NRA IS A MASTER WHEN IT
COMES TO PSYCHOLOGY.
LISTEN TO NRA EXECUTIVE VICE
PRESIDENT FROM EARLIER THIS
YEAR.
>> IF PRESIDENT OBAMA GETS ONE
MORE TERM IT WILL BREAK THE BACK
OF THE SECOND AMENDMENT OF THIS
COUNTRY.
THIS IS THE MOST DANGEROUS
ELECTION IN OUR LIFETIME IF YOU
ARE A SUPPORTER OF SECOND
AMENDMENT.
>> REALLY?
MR. OBAMA DID NOT PUSH FOR A
SINGLE PIECE OF GUN CONTROL
LEGISLATION IN HIS FIRST TERM.
NO MATTER.
IN THE NRA'S WORLD OBAMA'S
SECOND TERM SPELLS DOOM OR MAYBE
WHAT HAPPENED AT SANDY HOOK
DOES.
DICK'S SPORTING GOODS SAYS IT IS
BANNING SALES OF SOME
SEMI-AUTOMATIC GUNS NATIONWIDE.
THE LATE NRA FAMOUS FOR SAYING
HE WOULD GIVE US HIS GUN IF YOU
PRY IT FROM HIS HANDS.
>> FROM MY COLD, DEAD HANDS.
>> WHAT IS IT ABOUT GUNS THAT
CUTS TO THE CORE OF THE AMERICA
PSYCHE?
IS IT THE SECOND AMENDMENT WHICH
SAYS OUR RIGHT TO BEAR ARMS
SHOULD NOT BE INFRINGED OR IS IT
THAT GUN OWNERS SEE THEIR
RELATIONSHIP TO THIS DEMOCRACY
THROUGH THE EYES OF THE GUN
ISSUE?
WHAT DOES OWNING A GUN REPRESENT
TO YOU?
FACEBOOK.COM/CAROLCNN.
>>> KIDS IN EVERY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN EXCEPT FOR SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY ARE HEADED BACK TO
SCHOOL TODAY.
SOLEDAD O'BRIEN HAS BEEN IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
SHE JOINS US AGAIN.
>> Reporter: THAT'S RIGHT.
THE KIDS WILL BE ON A TWO-HOUR
DELAY.
THAT WILL GIVE THE TEACHERS A
LITTLE EXTRA TIME TO PREPARE FOR
THEIR CLASSES.
ALSO ON HAND AT EVERY SCHOOL,
GRIEF COUNSELORS.
IT IS A DIFFERENT WORLD TODAY
THAT THEY ARE GOING BACK TO.
I SPOKE WITH STEVE PERRY, THE
PRINCIPAL AND FOUNDER OF CAPITAL
PREPARATORY SCHOOL.
HERE IS WHAT HE TOLD ME.
IF YOU WERE AMONG THE PRINCIPALS
AND TEACHERS INSIDE THE
LOCATION, WHAT WOULD YOU BE
TELLING THEM?
>> I WOULD TELL MY COLLEAGUES IS
WHEN CHILDREN ASK QUESTIONS
INVITE THEM TO ASK QUESTIONS AND
RECOGNIZE THAT YOU NEED TO KEEP
THE TERMS BROAD BECAUSE WE DON'T
UNDERSTAND WHAT HAPPENED AND THE
BEST THING THAT WE CAN DO IS
FOCUS ON THE BROAD ALMOST
FANTASTICAL TERMS THAT BAD
THINGS SOMETIMES HAPPEN TO GOOD
PEOPLE AND THERE ARE NOW 20 MORE
ANGELS IN THE SKY.
>> Reporter: WHAT SHOULD THE
TONE THIS MORNING BE?
>> ALL POSITIVE.
YOU ARE GOING TO BE SAFE.
YOU ARE SAFE IN SCHOOLS.
>> Reporter: WE STILL DON'T KNOW
WHEN THE SANDY HOOK STUDENTS
WILL BE GOING BACK TO CLASS BUT
WHEN THEY DO THEY WILL BE GOING
TO A DIFFERENT SCHOOL IN NEARBY
MONROE, CONNECTICUT.
THAT SCHOOL IS ABOUT SEVEN MILES
AWAY FROM WHERE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY STANDS.
>> UNDERSTOOD.
ALL ACROSS THE COUNTRY SCHOOLS
CAN RELATE.
SAFETY IS GOING TO BECOME A BIG
ISSUE IN THE COUNTRY.
KEN TRUMP IS THE PRESIDENT OF
THE NATIONAL SCHOOL SAFETY
SERVICES.
>> GOOD MORNING.
>> HOW ARE PARENTS ACROSS THE
NATION REACTING TO THIS?
>> PARENTS FEEL HOPELESS,
HELPLESS AND TRULY POWERLESS IN
MANY CASES.
I AM GETTING E-MAILS FROM ACROSS
THE COUNTRY AS WELL AS TALKING
WITH PEOPLE IN MY OWN BACKYARD.
AND I THINK THAT PART OF THE
PROBLEM IS WE ARE LOOKING AT THE
ISSUE OF THE SCHOOL HAD
SECURITY.
THEY DID THE RIGHT THINGS AND IT
DIDN'T WORK.
I AM SUGGESTING TO PEOPLE THAT
THEY TAKE A SLIGHTLY DIFFERENT
LOOK IN SAYING WE DID NOT HAVE
THE DESIRED OUTCOME CAN EVERYONE
SURVIVING BUT I ALSO BELIEVE
THAT THE THINGS THAT THEY HAD IN
PLACE ACTUALLY CONTRIBUTED TO
SAVING MORE LIVES AND PREVENTING
GREATER LOSSES.
THERE ARE A COUPLE OF DIFFERENT
WAYS TO DO THAT.
PART OF THAT COMES INTO HELPING
FEEL THAT THEY ARE NOT HELPLESS
AND HOPELESS.
PARENTS ARE FRUSTRATED AND ON
EDGE AND LEADING TO CALLS ON FAR
OUT THINGS, AN ARMED OFFICER AT
EVERY SCHOOL.
POLICE OFFICERS IN SCHOOLS ARE
GOOD THINGS BUT PEOPLE ALMOST
WANT A ONE TO ONE RATIO IN SOME
CONVERSATIONS.
>> I CAN'T SAY THAT I BLAME
THEM.
HOW CAN PARENTS ADDRESS THEIR
FEARS IN MEANINGFUL WAYS?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
AS A SCHOOL SAFETY PROFESSIONAL
25 YEARS OF EXPERIENCE I AM
STILL ALSO A FATHER.
AS A FATHER I LIKE 100%
GUARANTEE.
AS A SAFETY PROFESSIONAL I KNOW
I CAN'T GIVE THAT SO I AM
CERTAINLY NOT CRITICIZING THEM
FOR THAT.
WHAT WE HAVE TO DO WITH KIDS IS
LOOK AT THEIR PHYSICAL AND
PSYCHOLOGICAL NEEDS.
PHYSICAL SECURITY AN ADULT
PRESENCE PARTICULARLY THOSE
ADULTS THAT THEY KNOW, HAVING
PARENTS COME BACK.
LAW ENFORCEMENT AND PARENTS,
PEOPLE THAT THEY ARE FAMILIAR
WITH.
FACES THEY KNOW AND HAVE SEEN
FOR A LONG TIME IS IMPORTANT.
THOSE COMING IN FROM OUTSIDE
HAVE CONSISTENT PHYSICAL
IDENTIFICATION, ARM BANDS, VESTS
AND STUFF.
THE PHYSICAL PART IS MANAGEABLE.
THE PART THAT IS GOING TO BE
VERY TRICKY IS THE PSYCHOLOGICAL
PART.
HOW ARE YOU DEALING WITH A
NUMBER OF ISSUES ON THAT END?
THE TRANSFER OF TRAUMA WHEN YOU
HAVE CHILDREN GOING FROM ONE
BUILDING TO ANOTHER AND YOU ARE
MIXING, ARE YOU TRANSFERRING
TRAUMA FROM ONE TO THE OTHER?
HOW DO YOU MANAGE THE TURF
ISSUES?
YOU BRING A GROUP OF KIDS IN
FROM SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AND HOW ARE THE RECEIVING
KIDS GOING TO FEEL?
ARE THEY GETTING LESS ATTENTION?
AGE APPROPRIATE CONVERSATIONS
WITH KIDS.
WE ARE NOT GOING TO TALK TO A
FIVE YEAR OLD THE SAME AS AN
EIGHT YEAR OLD.
UNDERSTAND THAT PEOPLE GRIEVE
DIFFERENTLY.
AND A HUGE ISSUE, CAROL, THAT WE
OFTEN MISS SO MUCH.
WHEN I HAVE GONE IN IN POST
CRISIS SITUATIONS IS DOING A
TREMENDOUS JOB OF TAKING CARE OF
THE KIDS AND FORGET THE ADULTS.
AND THAT PART IS CRITICAL.
PEOPLE GRIEVE AT DIFFERENT
TIMES.
I TALKED PERSONALLY WITH A
TEACHER WHO WAS IN A ROOM WHERE
A KID ATTACKED STUDENTS WITH A
TREE SAW AND A MACHETE AND A
COUPLE OF MONTHS LATER SHE
STARTED HAVING TRAUMATIC
EXPERIENCES.
I TALKED TO A TEACHER AT A
SCHOOL WHERE A KID BROUGHT AK-47
TO SCHOOL AND COMMITTED SUICIDE
AND THE TEACHER MONTHS LATER
WOULD FREEZE AT THE DROP OF A
BOOK.
AND THERE IS ONE OTHER ISSUE.
DOWN THE ROAD ONE OF THE HUGE
ISSUES THIS COMMUNITY IS GOING
TO HAVE TO DEAL WITH IS, DO WE
REOPEN THAT SCHOOL?
DO WE GO TO A NEW SCHOOL?
THERE WILL BE A LOT OF ADULT
CHALLENGES AND DISAGREEMENTS ON
THAT.
AND A WHOLE LOT OF PSYCHOLOGICAL
DISCUSSIONS.
HUGE ISSUES ON THE PSYCHOLOGICAL
END.
THE GOOD NEWS IS WE HAVE PEOPLE
WHO HAVE GONE THROUGH A GREAT
DEAL OF EFFORT TO PROVIDE THAT
SUPPORT IN LESSONS LEARNED FROM
PAST INCIDENTS.
IT IS SOMETHING THAT LIVES FOR
THE REST OF THEIR LIVES.
I TALKED WITH SOMEBODY FROM A
SCHOOL SHOOTING OVER A DECADE
AGO AND THIS INCIDENT LAST WEEK
OPENED UP THE WOUNDS.
>> I CAN TOTALLY UNDERSTAND
THAT.
THANKS FOR YOUR INSIGHT.
>>> HOW DO YOU MOVE ON FOLLOWING
A TRAGEDY LIKE THE ONE IN
NEWTOWN?
WE WILL HEAR FROM A MAN WHO HAD
TO DO THAT.
WE'RE ALL HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR IN THE GULF,
WE'VE DECIDED TO
PUT ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
'CAUSE ALL OUR STATES ARE GREAT.
AND NOW IS WHEN THE GULF
GETS EVEN BETTER.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE OR
JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
ENJOY THE WILDLIFE
AND NATURAL BEAUTY.
AND DON'T FORGET
OUR AMAZING SEAFOOD.
SO COME TO THE GULF,
YOU'LL HAVE A GREAT TIME.
ESPECIALLY IN ALABAMA.
YOU MEAN MISSISSIPPI.
THAT'S FLORIDA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP AND ALL
OF US WHO CALL THE GULF HOME.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
>> Reporter: THERE ARE ONLY A
FEW EVECHBTS THAT HAVE REACHED
THE MAGNITUDE OF WHAT HAPPENED
HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
ONE OF THOSE WAS THE BOMBING OF
THE FEDERAL BUILDING IN OKLAHOMA
CITY.
I ASKED THE GOVERNOR HOW THEY
MANAGED TO MOVE ON.
>> IT IS AN INSTANT CATACLYSIM
FOR THE FAMILIES AND FIRST
RESPONDERS.
THE CLIMB OUT IS LONG AND
SEARING AND VERY DIFFICULT.
TODAY 17 YEARS AFTER THE
OKLAHOMA CITY BOMBING WITH
PRIVATE FUNDS WE ARE STILL
PUTTING CHILDREN THROUGH
COLLEGE, PROVIDING COUNSELING,
PARTICULAR TO FIRST RESPONDERS,
FIREFIGHTERS AND POLICE OFFICERS
AND EVEN PROVIDING MEDICAL CARE
FOR A NUMBER OF THE BADLY
INJURED.
THE ONE THING ABOUT NEWTOWN, IT
IS A COMMUNITY.
SO STITCHING TOGETHER, HOLDING
HANDS TOGETHER, UNDERSTANDING
YOUR NEIGHBOR IS REALLY YOUR
NEIGHBOR IF NOT A FAMILY MEMBER.
THIS IS GOING TO BE A LONG TIME
CRAWLING OUT, SCRATCHING
YOURSELF OUT BECAUSE IT IS GOING
TO BE SEARING.
WE HAVE HAD SUICIDES.
JUST A LOT OF AGONY AFTER THE
OKLAHOMA CITY BOMBING.
AND I AM AFRAID THAT THE TRAGEDY
IN NEWTOWN WILL TAKE A LONG TIME
TO RECOVER.
>> Reporter: IT JUST SOUNDS SO
BRUTAL.
YOU MENTIONED THE FIRST
RESPONDERS.
AND I REMEMBER SEEING WHEN THE
PRESIDENT CAME TO THE INTERFACE
VIGIL AND THE FIRST RESPONDERS
WALKED IN EVERYONE CHEERED AND
CLAPPED AND PATTED THEM ON THE
BACK.
I THINK THEY ARE OFTEN
FORGOTTEN.
WE DON'T THINK ABOUT THEIR
MENTAL HEALTH AND HOW BRUTALLY
DIFFICULT IT MUST HAVE BEEN FOR
THEM TO GO INSIDE THAT SCHOOL
AND SEE THE MASSACRE WITH SMALL
CHILDREN, MANY OF THOSE
RESPONDERS PARENTS THEMSELVES.
>> THAT'S THE POINT BECAUSE
RIGHT NOW I SAW THE UNIVERSITY
OF CONNECTICUT IS PUTTING
TOGETHER A SCHOLARSHIP FUND.
SURELY THERE ARE PRIVATE CHECKS
ARRIVING, PRIVATE TRANSFERS OF
MONEY.
I THINK IT IS IMPORTANT THAT A
COMMUNITY FOUNDATION OR PERHAPS
THE UNITED WAY INITIALLY PUT
TOGETHER A PLAN FOR HOW DO WE
ADDRESS THE PROBLEMS BECAUSE
SOME PEOPLE ARE GOING TO NEED
LONG TERM COUNSELING.
THE FIRST RESPONDERS
PARTICULARLY PEOPLE NEED TO BE
VERY SENSITIVE TO THOSE
ABSOLUTELY STUNNING, SEARING,
SHOCKING UNFORGETTABLE MOMENTS
OF THOSE WONDERFUL LITTLE
CHILDREN.
PEOPLE NEED TO SIT AROUND THE
TABLE TOGETHER AND WORK IT OUT
BUT REALIZE THEY ARE GOING TO BE
IN THIS BUSINESS FOR A LONG
TIME.
>> Reporter: 168 PEOPLE WERE
KILLED IN THAT BOMBING INCLUDING
19 CHILDREN.
SOME SOCIAL MEDIA USERS HAVE
BEEN POSTING FALSE INFORMATION
ABOUT THE SANDY HOOK CASE AND
NOW POLICE ARE SAYING THESE
FOLKS COULD FACE CHARGES.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT THAT STRAIGHT
AHEAD.
BACK IN A MOMENT.
...and now...
You!
[ giggles ]
♪ The one and only, Cheerios
>>> GOOD MORNING.
NEARLY 100 MILLION PEOPLE USE
INSTAGRAM BUT THE SOCIAL NETWORK
MAY FORCE MANY OF THEM TO DO A
DOUBLE TAKE.
ALISON KOSIK IS AT THE NEW YORK
STOCK EXCHANGE TO EXPLAIN THIS.
>> SO IT MAKES YOU WONDER WHAT
ARE THE SOCIAL MEDIA COMPANIES
THINKING.
FIRST THERE WAS FACEBOOK.
THEY CHANGED THEIR TERMS OF
SERVICE AND NOW INSTAGRAM IS
LOOKING TO DO THAT.
YOU LOOK ON SOCIAL MEDIA AND
PEOPLE ARE NOT HAPPY ABOUT THIS.
WHAT INSTAGRAM ANNOUNCED
YESTERDAY IS THAT IT IS CHANGING
ITS TERMS INCLUDING THAT IT CAN
SELL YOUR PHOTOS TO THIRD
PARTIES FOR ADVERTISING.
I WANT YOU TO LOOK AT THE KEY
PARAGRAPH WHERE PART OF IT SAYS
YOU AGREE THAT A BUSINESS OR
OTHER ENTITY MAY PAY US TO
DISPLAY YOUR USER NAME,
LIKENESS, PHOTOS WITHOUT ANY
COMPENSATION TO YOU.
IF YOU POST A GREAT PICTURE OF
YOU ON THE BEACH OF YOUR BEACH
VACATION, THE HOTEL OR TOWN THAT
OWNS THE BEACH COULD BUY YOUR
PHOTO TO USE BUT YOU DON'T GET
ANY OF THE MONEY.
HERE IS THE OTHER PROBLEM WITH
THIS.
THERE IS NO WAY TO OPT OUT
UNLESS YOU DELETE YOUR INSTAGRAM
ACCOUNT ALL TOGETHER BEFORE
JANUARY 16th.
IF YOU DO IT AFTER JANUARY
16thER THEY CAN GRAB THOSE
PHOTOS, TOO.
>> ONE WAS A KID IN THE PICTURE.
>> EXACTLY.
THE BIGGEST COMPLAINT IS IF YOU
ARE AN UNDER AGED USER YOU ARE
NOT EXEMPT FROM THESE POLICIES.
IF YOU ARE UNDER 18 YOU ARE
AGREEING THAT YOUR PARENTS KNOW
YOUR NAME AND LIKENESS CAN BE
USED IN THE ADS.
MOST PARENTS WOULDN'T AGREE.
ON THE KIDS' PART IF I TAKE
PHOTOS OF MY KIDS PLAYING ON THE
BEACH, THAT IS FAIR GAME, TOO,
FOR INSTAGRAM TO GRAB IT AND USE
IT, AS WELL.
THIS WOULD GOOD GIN ON JANUARY
16.
PEOPLE ARE SAYING THEY PLAN TO
DELETE THEIR ACCOUNTS
IMMEDIATELY.
IF YOU ARE ON INSTAGRAM AND YOU
ARE ONLY IN IT FOR THE FILTERS
YOU CAN GO TO PIC U AND SNAP
BUCKET.
TWITTER ADDED THEIR OWN FILTERS.
THERE ARE CHOICES IF YOU ARE
LOOKING TO CHANGE HOW YOUR
PICTURES LOOK.
>> GOOD ADVICE.
ALISON KOSIK REPORTING LIVE FROM
THE NEW YORK STOCK EXCHANGE.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS SHELDON, WHOSE LONG DY
SETTING UP THE NEWS
STARTS WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND A CHOICE.
TAKE TYLENOL OR TAKE ALEVE,
THE #1 RECOMMENDED PAIN
RELIEVER BY ORTHOPEDIC DOCTORS.
JUST TWO ALEVE
CAN KEEP PAIN AWAY ALL DAY.
BACK TO THE NEWS.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME FOR CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
[Music:
Artist: Willy Moon
♪ Everybody well don't
you know it's me now? ♪
♪ Yeah who's it,
who's it huh? ♪
♪ Willy's back with a
brand new beat now, ♪
♪ Yeah doin' it doin' it up!
♪ Heyyy yeah, tryin'
to bite my style! ♪
♪ Heyyy yeah, how you
like me now? ♪
♪ Na na na na na na na na
♪ And everybody go uh!
>>> IT IS HARD TO FATHOM ANYONE
WOULD ACTUALLY DO THIS BUT MAYBE
WE SHOULDN'T BE SURPRISED.
MANY HAVE BEEN POSTING FAKE
INFORMATION ABOUT THE SANDY HOOK
SHOOTER, INFORMATION THAT HAS
CONFUSED CONNECTICUT POLICE IN
THE MIDST OF A VERY DIFFICULT
INVESTIGATION.
STATE POLICE HAVE HAD ENOUGH.
>> THERE HAS BEEN MISINFORMATION
COMING FROM PEOPLE POSING AS THE
SHOOTER IN THIS CASE, POSING,
USING OTHER I.D.s, MIMICKING
THIS CRIME AND CRIME SCENE AND
ACTIVITY THAT TOOK PLACE IN THIS
COMMUNITY.
PROSECUTION WILL TAKE PLACE WHEN
PEOPLE PERPETRATING
MISINFORMATION ARE IDENTIFIED.
>> AS AN INTERNET PRIVACY AND
SECURITY LAWYER PERRY KNOWS
ABOUT FAKE POSTS AND POSERS.
SHE WORKS WITH FACEBOOK TO
PROTECT THE REAL ACCOUNTS OF
FAMOUS ACTORS AND OTHER V.I.P.s.
>> HOW ARE YOU?
>> I'M GOOD.
SO WILL THE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE HAVE TROUBLE TRACKING
THESE POSERS DOWN?
>> THEY CAN PROBABLY TRACK THEM
DOWN BUT IT IS NOT SO EASY TO
PUT THEM IN JAIL.
I THINK THE STATE POLICE VERY
HIGH CYBER CRIME EXPERTS IN THE
CASE, SENATOR BLUMENTHAL RAISED
THEM WELL, NEED TO LOOK OFFLINE
FOR MORE RELIABLE FORMS THAN
ONLINE.
YOU WILL SEE TROLLS AND OTHERS
USING THIS TO GET THE ATTENTION
THAT THEY CRAVE.
>> BUT POLICE CAN OFTEN FIND
VALUABLE INFORMATION ONLINE.
SO IN THEIR MIND THEY NEED TO
PAY ATTENTION TO SOCIAL MEDIA
AND THEN YOU HAVE THESE PEOPLE
POSTING FAKE INFORMATION.
>> WE NEED TO FIND RELIABLE
SOURCES ONLINE.
THERE ARE WAYS TO AUTHENT KATE
THAT.
WE NEED TO RECOGNIZE THAT A LOT
OF PEOPLE DOING THESE PRANKS MAY
BE COVERED BY FREE SPEECH OF THE
FIRST AMENDMENT.
WE HAVE TO BE CAREFUL HOW WE
INVESTIGATE THIS.
THIS IS A VERY SERIOUS SITUATION
AND SOMETHING WE NEED TO MAKE
SURE IS NEVER REPEATED.
>> YOU ARE TALKING FIRST
AMENDMENT RIGHTS.
IT IS A FREE COUNTRY.
YOU CAN POST ANYTHING ONLINE TO
A POINT.
WHEN THE LIEUTENANT VANCE SAYS
YOU ARE GOING TO BE PROSECUTED,
WILL YOU BE?
>> WELL, IN SOME CASES, YES.
IF THERE IS A THREAT AGAINST
SERIOUS BODILY HARM AND PROPERTY
AND AN INTENT TO EFFECT THE
POLICE INVESTIGATION OR STEALING
SOMEONE'S IDENTITY THERE MAY BE
GROUNDS FOR THAT.
IF THEY ARE JUST POSTING
INFORMATION THAT MAY BE
CONFUSING THERE MAY NOT BE.
I WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT THEY
USE ALL OF THEIR ENERGY IN THE
RIGHT WAYS AND A LOT OF BIG
NETWORKS ARE VERY HELPFUL THERE
AND THEY ARE PROTECTING THE
IDENTITY OF CELEBRITIES WHO HAVE
PEOPLE MASK RAIDING AS THEM ALL
THE TIME.
WHAT THEY DO IS THEY SAY THINGS
AND DO THINGS THAT THEY HOPE
WILL BE ATTRIBUTED TO THE
CELEBRITY AND MANY OF THOSE ARE
FAKES.
>> AS FAR AS FACEBOOK IS
CONCERNED WHAT RESPONSIBILITY
DOES FACEBOOK HAVE TO KICK THESE
PEOPLE OFFLINE?
>> WELL, RESPONSIBILITY OR WHAT
EFFORTS DO THEY TAKE?
I THINK IT IS LESS ABOUT
RESPONSIBILITY AND MORE ABOUT
THEM GOING ABOVE AND BEYOND.
WHEN YOU ARE DEALING WITH
CELEBRITIES AND VIPS THEY ARE
VERY CAREFUL TO CREATE A UNIT SO
THAT THE MANAGEMENT OF THE VIPS
OR CELEBRITIES CAN REACH OUT
SAYING THOSE SIX ACCOUNTS AREN'T
ME.
THEY CAN MAKE SURE NO ONE IS
POSING AS YOU ON FACEBOOK.
>> SO IS FACEBOOK DOING
SOMETHING SIMILAR TO THE SHOOTER
IN THIS CASE?
>> I'M SORRY?
ARE THEY CATCHING PEOPLE POSING
AS THE SHOOTER?
>> YEAH.
FACEBOOK.
>> FACEBOOK IS WORKING WITH LAW
ENFORCEMENT VERY CLOSELY TO GIVE
THEM ANY INFORMATION THEY NEED
TO DO THIS.
THEY DON'T TO MY KNOWLEDGE HAVE
ANY SPECIAL WATCHES OUT FOR ANY
OF THE NAMES OF THE VICTIMS OR
SHOOTING, ANYONE INVOLVED.
PEOPLE MAY BE ABLE TO CREATE
THOSE ACCOUNTS.
THEY ARE WORKING VERY CLOSELY
WITH CONNECTICUT LAW ENFORCEMENT
IN HELPING TRACK DOWN THINGS
THEY NEED TRACKED.
>> THANKS  FOR SHARING YOUR
INSIGHT WITH US.
WE APPRECIATE IT.
>> THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME BACK.
IT IS A VERY SAD TIME AND
HOPEFULLY WE CAN WORK TOGETHER.
>> I HOPE SO.
THANKS SO MUCH.
>>> WHAT DOES OWNING A GUN
REPRESENT TO YOU?
YOUR RESPONSES NEXT.
We are gathered here today to
celebrate the union of
Tim and Laura.
It's amazing how appreciative
ople are when you tell them
they could save a lot of money
on their car insurance
by switching to GEICO...they may
even make you their best man.
May I have the rings please?
Ah, Helzberg Diamonds.
Nice choice, Mate.
...and now in the presence
of these guests
we join this loving couple.
Oh dear...
GEICO. 15 minutes could save you
15% or more on car insurance.
♪ HARK HOW THE BELLS,
SWEET SILVER BELLS ♪
♪ ALL SEEM TO SAY
THROW CARE AWAY ♪
♪ FROM EVERYWHERE,
FILLING THE AIR ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
CHEX PARTY MIX.
EASY 15-MINUTE
HOMEMADE RECIPES
YOU JUST POP IN A MICROWAVE.
LIKE CARAMEL CHOCOLATE
DRIZZLES.
HAPPIER HOLIDAYS.
CHEX PARTY MIX.
>>> TALK BACK QUESTION TODAY.
WHAT DOES OWNING A GUN REPRESENT
TO YOU.
THIS FROM KIARA.
OWNING A GUN MEANS NOTHING.
I THINK PEOPLE WHO OWN GUNS ARE
SCARED TO LIVE LIFE WITHOUT
SOMETHING THAT MAKES THEM FEEL
POWERFUL.
DAVEN, SECURITY, PROTECTION,
SELF-DEFENSE ALL NECESSARY FOR
LIVING FREE.
THIS FROM BOB.
AN ARCHAIC REMNANT OF THE 18th
CENTURY.
THIS FROM ROBIN.
WE USE OUR GUNS FOR HUNTING
FOOD.
WE FILL OUR FREEZER WITH MEATS
AND THAT IS WHAT WE USE OUR GUNS
FOR.
I WOULD DEFINITELY NOT WANT MY
LIFE TAKEN AWAY.
LOTS OF RESPONSES AGAIN THIS
MORNING.
I APPRECIATE IT.
FACEBOOK.COM/CAROLCNN.
CNN "NEWSROOM" WITH ASHLEY
CONTINUES AFTER THE BREAK.
PAIREH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
A BODY AT REST
TENDS TO STAY AT REST...
WHILE A BODY IN MOTION
TENDS TO STAY IN MOTION.
STAYING ACTIVE CAN ACTUALLY
EASE ARTHRITIS SYMPTOMS.
BUT IF YOU HAVE ARTHRITIS,
STAYING ACTIVE
CAN BE DIFFICULT.
PRESCRIPTION CELEBREX
CAN HELP RELIEVE ARTHRITIS PAIN
SO YOUR BODY
CAN STAY IN MOTION.
BECAUSE JUST ONE
200MG CELEBREX A DAY
CAN PROVIDE 24 HOUR RELIEF
FOR MANY WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND INFLAMMATION.
PLUS, IN CLINICAL STUDIES,
CELEBREX IS PROVEN TO IMPROVE
DAILY PHYSICAL FUNCTION
SO MOVING IS EASIER.
CELEBREX CAN BE TAKEN WITH
OR WITHOUT FOOD.
AND IT'S NOT A NARCOTIC.
YOU AND YOUR DOCTOR
SHOULD BALANCE THE BENEFITS
WITH THE RISKS.
ALL PRESCRIPTION NSAIDS,
LIKE CELEBREX, IBUPROFEN,
NAPROXEN, AND MELOXICAM
HAVE THE SAME
CARDIOVASCULAR WARNING.
THEY ALL MAY INCREASE
THE CHANCE
OF HEART ATTACK OR STROKE,
WHICH CAN LEAD TO DEATH.
THIS CHANCE INCREASES
IF YOU HAVE HEART DISEASE
OR RISK FACTORS
SUCH AS HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE
OR WHEN NSAIDS ARE TAKEN
FOR LONG PERIODS.
NSAIDS, INCLUDING CELEBREX,