MEANS THAT THOSE PARENTS WHO
WERE NOT REUNITED WITH THEIR
CHILDREN, THEY KNOW THAT THOSE
CHILDREN'S BODIES ARE STILL IN
THE SCHOOL TONIGHT, THOSE
TEACHERS, THOSE ADULTS WHO WERE
ALSO SHOT, THE SIX OF THEM, THE
BODIES ARE ALSO IN THE SCHOOL
TONIGHT.
POSITIVE IDENTIFICATIONS HAVE TO
BE DONE.
THE CORONER'S OFFICE HAS A HUGE
TASK.
THE INVESTIGATION OF THE SHOTS,
OVER 1 0 100 ROUNDS BY ONE
ESTIMATION.
THERE IS A MASSIVE EMOTIONAL
PRONG FOR THIS COMMUNITY TO HEA
WE HEAD MANY TO THE HOLIDAYS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
ASHLEIGH BANFIELD REPORTING.
PIERS MORGAN TONIGHT STARTS NOW.
>>> BREAKING NEWS, YOU ARE
LOOKING AT A COMMUNITY IN
MOURNING AFTER ONE OF THE WORST
MASS SHOOTINGS IN HISTORY.
POLICE SAY A GUNMAN KILLED 20
YOUNG CHILDREN FROM 5 TO 10
YEARS OLD.
THE SHOOTINGS TOOK PLACE IN TWO
ROOMS IN ONE SECTION OF THE
SCHOOL AND HE KILLED AT LEAST
SIX ADULTS BEFORE CAN KILLING
HIMSELF.
POLICE FOUND THE BODY OF THE
SUSPECT'S MOTHER'S HOME EARLIER
IN THE DAY.
A PRAYER VIGIL TOOK PLACE.
HUNDREDS IN ATTENDANCE.
AT THE WHITE HOUSE ANOTHER VIGIL
WAS HELD.
PEOPLE HOLDING CANDLES BUT THE
CALL WAS FOR MORE GUN CONTROL.
MANY SAY THE TRAGEDY DEMANDS
TOUGHER LEGISLATION.
A VISIBLY SHAKEN PRESIDENT OBAMA
OFFERED THESE WORDS ABOUT THE
MASS KILLING.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS.
MEN AND WOMEN WHO DEVOTED THEIR
LIVES TO HELPING OUR CHILDREN
FULFILL THEIR DREAMS.
>> HIGHLY EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT
OBAMA REFLECTING HOW MOST OF THE
NATION WOULD HAVE BEEN FEELING
AND TONIGHT POLICE HAVE
IDENTIFIED THE KILLER AS ADAM
LANZA.
THIS IS HIS BROTHER RYAN LANZA
BEING TAKEN INTO QUESTIONING.
MUCH MORE ON THE SHOOTER AHEAD.
I SPOKE WITH THE FORMER
CLASSMATE.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI HAS NEW DETAILS
FROM OUTSIDE THE SCHOOL.
A DESPERATE DAY FOR THE SCHOOL
AND THE FAMILIES OF THE POOR
CHILDREN AND FOR AMERICA.
WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT THE PERSON
WHO PERPETRATED THE HIDEOUS
CRIME?
>> IT IS SO HEART BREAKING.
WE ARE LEARNING HE IS
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA.
WE KNOW, ACCORDING TO OUR
SOURCES, THAT FOR WHATEVER
REASON WHEN HE CAME TO THE
SCHOOL THIS DAY, HE WAS WEARING
WHAT IS DESCRIBED TO ME AS BLACK
BATTLE FATIGUES AND A MILITARY
VEST.
HE CAME ARMED WITH THREE
WEAPONS.
TWO OF THEM HAND GUNS.
ONE AS A GLOCK AND ANOTHER AS A
SIG SAUER AND A THIRD POLICE
FOUND IN THE VEHICLE.
THE TWO WEAPONS WERE FOUND ON
HIM IN THE SCHOOL.
THE THIRD WAS FOUND, THE BUSH
MASTER WHICH IS A SEMI AUTOMATIC
WAS FOUND IN A CAR OUTSIDE THE
SCHOOL.
WHAT LED HIM TO THIS?
WE DON'T KNOW.
WE DO KNOW THIS.
POLICE HAVE QUESTIONED BOTH HIS
BROTHER AND HIS FATHER.
HIS BROTHER WAS TAKEN INTO
CUSTODY FOR QUESTIONING ONLY.
HE IS NOT BEING CALLED A
SUSPECT.
FROM HIS APARTMENT IN HOBOKEN,
NEW JERSEY.
WE UNDERSTAND THE FATHER WAS
ALSO QUESTIONED BY AUTHORITIES
HERE IN THE NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
AREA.
THE FATHER IS DIVORCED FROM
NANCY LANZA.
SHE IS THE MOTHER OF THE TWO WHO
IS A SCHOOL TEACHER AND COUNTED
AMONG THE DEAD.
HER BODY WAS FOUND IN A
RESIDENCE HERE IN THE NEWTOWN
AREA, AS WELL.
BELIEVE IT OR NOT, PIERS, THE
WEAPONS ACCORDING TO AUTHORITIES
WERE OWNED BY THE MOTHER, NANCY
LANZA IN THIS CASE.
NOT BY THE SHOOTER.
STILL TRYING TO PIECE TOGETHER A
MOTIVE.
THERE SIGNS WE ARE HEARING FOR
OUR SOURCES THAT THE SHOOTER MAY
HAVE SUFFERED FROM SOME KIND OF
PERSONALITY DISORDER.
DID HE LEAVE NOTES BEHIND?
DID HE TELL ANYONE WHAT HE WAS
PLANNING TO DO?
AMONG THE MANY QUESTIONS THAT WE
ALL HAVE TONIGHT.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH INDEED.
I WANT TO TURN TO ASHLEIGH
BANFIELD.
SHE'S IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
AS WELL.
I WAS WATCHING WHEN YOU WERE
SPEAKING TO WOLF BLITZER AND YOU
BECAME VERY EMOTIONAL.
TWO OF YOUR CHILDREN WENT TO
SCHOOL IN CONNECTICUT AND YOU
WERE NOT SURE WHAT WAS HAPPENING
WITH THEM.
THANKFULLY, THEY WERE OKAY.
BUT THIS IS EVERY PARENT'S
NIGHTMARE.
FROM WHAT WE UNDERSTAND THE
BODIES OF STILL LYING THERE ON
WHAT THE POLICE ARE CALLING THE
CRIME SCENE OF THE SCHOOL.
THE PARENTS CAN'T EVEN SEE THEM.
IT'S AN UNIMAGINABLE HORROR.
>> THERE IS NO OTHER WAY TO PUT
IT.
UNIMAGINABLE HORROR AND AN EVIL
VISITED UPON THE COMMUNITY
ACCORDING TO THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT WHO SPOKE HERE
EARLIER.
ANOTHER DETAIL FOR YOU THAT I
WANT TO SHARE ABOUT HOW SOME OF
THESE PARENTS LEARNED THEY
WOULDN'T BE SEEING THEIR
CHILDREN AGAIN.
I THINK YOU ALREADY KNOW THE
DETAIL THAT MANY OF THE CHILDREN
WERE RUSHED OUT OF THE SCHOOL.
OUT OF THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
BY THE POLICE AND TEACHERS AND
RACED ON FOOT TO A NEARBY FIRE
STATION WHICH BECAME THE STAGING
AREA.
THEY WERE ROBO CALLS THAT WENT
OUT.
WE HEARD THE ROBOCALLS SAYING
PARENTS OF THE SANDY HOOK
STUDENTS, COME TO THIS FIRE
STATION TO BE REUNITED WITH YOUR
CHILDREN.
THROUGHOUT THE DAY THERE WAS ONE
AREA WITHIN THAT FIRE STATION
WHERE THE CHILDREN WERE KEPT AND
THEY WERE SHOWN MOVIES UNTIL
THEIR PARENTS COULD COME AND
FIND THEM.
THERE WAS ANOTHER AREA WHERE A
NUMBER OF THE PARENTS WERE
MILLING ABOUT, WAITING FOR
STUDENTS TO BE BROUGHT INTO THE
FIRE STATION.
YOU CAN IMAGINE IT WAS A CHAOTIC
SCENE FOR SOMETIME.
SLOWLY BUT SURELY OVER THE
COURSE OF THE DAY PARENTS ARRIVE
AND CHILDREN WERE TAKEN AWAY AND
PARENTS CONTINUED TO WAIT AND
OTHER CHILDREN DIDN'T ARRIVE AND
ULTIMATELY THERE WAS A MOMENT
WHERE THEY HAD TO TELL THE
WAITING PARENTS THERE WILL BE NO
MORE REUNIONS TONIGHT.
I'M TOLD FROM SOMEONE WHO WAS
INSIDE THAT AREA IN A ROOM
ADJACENT THAT AT THE MOMENT THE
PARENTS WERE TOLD THERE WOULD BE
NO MORE CHILDREN COMING THERE
WERE WAILS THAT WERE RELEASED.
THE PERSON WHO TOLD ME THIS SHE
SAID SHE COMPLETELY BROKE DOWN.
THERE WAS A NURSE ON HAND WHO
VOLUNTEERED HAVING WORKED TWO
DECADES IN THE BUSINESS.
HER BROTHER TELLING ME THAT SHE
JUST WANTED TO BE THERE AND HELP
IN ANY WAY SHE COULD AS A GRIEF
COUNSELLOR AND WAS PRESENT AT
THAT TIME AS WELL.
A HORRIFYING MOMENT IF YOU CAN
IMAGINE BEING THOSE PARENT WHO
IS WAITED AND WAITED AND WAITED
ONLY TO HEAR THIS AND ULTIMATELY
LIKE YOU SAID, THEY KNOW THE
BODIES OF THEIR CHILDREN ARE
STILL IN THAT SCHOOL TONIGHT.
>> IT'S HARD TO IMAGINE ANYTHING
WORSE IN THE WORLD.
THANK YOU FOR NOW.
I WILL BE JOINED BY THE MAYOR OF
DANBURY RIGHT NEXT TO NEWTOWN.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING ME.
THIS IS ALMOST BEYOND
DESCRIPTION, BEYOND ANY
UNDERSTANDING.
HOW IS THE COMMUNITY DEALING
WITH THIS OR ARE THEY?
WHAT CAN YOU DO?
>> WELL, OBVIOUSLY IT'S BEEN A
HORRIFIC DAY IN THE GREATER
DANBURY AREA AND PARTICULARLY
THE TOWN OF NEWTOWN.
OUR HEART GOES OUT TO THE
INDIVIDUALS WHO LOST LOVED ONES
TODAY AND OBVIOUSLY THE CHILDREN
AND THE STAFF AND EVERYBODY
ELSE.
IT'S BEEN AN INCREDIBLY
DIFFICULT DAY.
I HAVE TO TELL YOU, THEY HAVE
BEEN WORKING HARD AND CAN'T BE
WITH US RIGHT NOW BUT IS DOING
WHAT NEEDS TO BE DONE.
THE FIRST RESPONDERS WERE
TREMENDOUS AND THE STAFF HAVE
BEEN HEROIC IN TERMS OF THEIR
APPROACH TO THIS.
IT'S AN ABSOLUTE INTERNATIONAL
TRAGEDY AND CRISIS.
>> I UNDERSTAND THAT YOU KNEW
THE PRINCIPAL OF THE SCHOOL WHO
ALSO WAS KILLED.
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
I HAD THE HONOR OF WORKING IN
THE SAME SCHOOL SYSTEM AND VERY
CLOSE PROXIMITY TO DAWN WHO
PASSED AWAY TODAY.
SHE WAS A TEACHER IN THE SCHOOL
SYSTEM AND ELEVATED UP THROUGH
THE RANKS AND ENDED UP THE
PRINCIPAL HERE IN NEWTOWN.
A COMMITTED, HARDWORKING AND
DEDICATED EDUCATOR.
SOMEONE WHO CARED DEEPLY ABOUT
THE KIDS AND PUT KIDS FIRST IN
EVERY FACET AND EVERY WAY IN
WHICH SHE EXECUTED HER JOB AND
SOMEBODY WHO WE ALL ADMIRED
WORKING WITH HER CHILDREN AS A
PROFESSIONAL.
>> EXTREMELY SAD DAY AND I
APPRECIATE YOU JOINING ME.
I CAN ONLY WISH YOU THE VERY
BEST.
WE ARE TRYING TO REBUILD THE
COMMUNITY.
DID YOU KNOW IF THERE PLANS FOR
MORE VIGILS TOMORROW?
>> THERE ARE VIGILS SCHEDULED
THROUGHOUT THE WEEKEND.
IN ADDITION THAT, CONNECTICUT
ITSELF IS HAVING A SIMULTANEOUS
VIGIL THAT THEY ARE TRYING TO
ORGANIZE RIGHT NOW WHERE EACH
TOWN AND VILLAGE AND CITY WILL
TAKE A MOMENT OUT AND SPEND TIME
REFLECTING AND MAYBE STARTING
ONCE WE GET THROUGH THIS INITIAL
HORRENDOUS SHOCK AND REFLECTING
A LITTLE BIT ABOUT OUR PUBLIC
POLICY POSITIONS AS THEY RELATE
TO THINGS LIKE GUN CONTROL AND
HOW WE DEAL WITH FOLKS THAT ARE
MENTALLY DISABLED.
ONCE WE UNDERSTAND THIS HORRIFIC
TRAGEDY THAT OCCURRED.
THAT CONVERSATION WILL BE
STARTED OVER THE NEXT COUPLE OF
WEEKS.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH INDEED
FOR JOINING ME.
>> THANK YOU, PIERS.
>> WE CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT IT WAS
LIKE IN THE SCHOOL.
SOFIA LOBINSKI WAS THERE AND
JUST 8 YEARS OLD.
SHE JOINS ME WITH HER BROTHER,
BRENDA, THANK YOU BOTH FOR
JOINING ME.
IF I MAY START WITH YOU, BRENDA.
THIS IS EVERY MOTHER'S
NIGHTMARE.
WHEN WAS THE FIRST YOU HEARD
ABOUT THIS AND HOW DID YOU HEAR?
>> I RECEIVED A CALL FROM THE
SCHOOL SYSTEM FROM THE
SUPERINTENDENT SAYING THAT THERE
WAS A SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN, BUT
DIDN'T SAY IT WAS A SCHOOL.
THAT THE SCHOOLS WERE ON
LOCKDOWN.
I WASN'T TOO CONCERNED BECAUSE I
DIDN'T KNOW WHERE IT HAPPENED.
I RECEIVED A TEXT ON MY PHONE
FROM A NEWS ORGANIZATION AND
THEY SAID THAT SANDY HOOK SCHOOL
HAD A SHOOTING.
I GOT IN MY CAR AND I WENT OVER
TO THE SCHOOL AND THERE WERE
ALREADY STATE POLICE AND THE
FIRE AND NEWTOWN POLICE.
>> WHEN YOU GOT THERE, OBVIOUSLY
SCENES OF COMPLETE CHAOS, HOW
QUICKLY WAS IT THAT YOU REALIZED
YOUR DAUGHTER WAS SAFE?
>> OKAY.
WHEN I GOT THERE, THERE WAS
COMPLETE CHAOS, BUT I DID SEE
MOMS AND A NEIGHBOR AND ASKED
THEM WHAT HAPPENED AND THEY SAID
THEY DIDN'T KNOW.
THAT THERE WAS A SHOOTING AND I
SAW A NEIGHBOR LIKE I SAID AND
HE SAID THEY CARRIED OUT A
LITTLE GIRL AND SHE LOOKED LIKE
SHE WAS DEAD.
INSTANTLY I PANICKED BECAUSE OF
MY BABY HERE, BUT THANKFULLY NO
SOONER HE SAID THAT I LOOKED
TOWARDS THE KIDS BEING BROUGHT
FROM THE SCHOOL TO THE FIREHOUSE
AND I SAW HER CLASS AND I RAN UP
AND I SAID WHERE IS SOFIA AND
THEY SAID SHE IS OKAY.
SHE'S COMING.
I SAW HER WITH HER TEACHER AND
WE ALL WERE TAKEN INTO THE
FIREHOUSE AND KEPT SO THEY COULD
DO A ROLL CALL AND MAKE SURE ALL
THE STUDENTS WERE ACCOUNTED FOR.
>> SOFIA, IT'S BEEN A TERRIFYING
DAY FOR YOU AND YOUR FRIENDS.
WHAT DID YOU THINK WAS
HAPPENING.
WERE YOU AWARE SOMEBODY WAS
FIRING A GUN IN THE SCHOOL?
>> CAN YOU HEAR, HONEY.
>> NOT REALLY.
>> WHAT SHE TOLD ME IS THEY
HEARD POPS IN THE HALLWAY.
THE TEACHER TOLD ME ALSO,
COURTNEY MARTIN IS MY HERO, SHE
LOCKED THE DOOR IMMEDIATELY AND
BROUGHT ALL THE KIDS TO A CORNER
OF THE ROOM WHERE THEY STAYED
THERE.
THEY WERE SCARED AND SHAKEN, BUT
THEY DIDN'T KNOW WHAT WAS GOING
ON UNTIL LATER WHEN THEY WERE
BROUGHT INTO THE FIREHOUSE.
POLICE CAME AND KNOCKED ON THE
DOOR AND SAID IT'S OKAY, YOU CAN
COME OUT.
THEY GUIDED THEM TO THE BACK OF
THE SCHOOL AND THEY WALKED OVER
TO THE FIREHOUSE.
THAT'S WHERE I CAUGHT UP WITH
SOFIA.
>> HOW IS SOFIA NOW?
IT MUST HAVE BEEN A TRAUMATIC
EXPERIENCE FOR ALL THE CHILDREN
WHO SURVIVED THIS.
>> I THINK SHE IS NUMB RIGHT
NOW.
SHE IS A PRETTY BRIGHT KID AND
SHE HAS A BIG SUPPORT STAFF AT
HOME AND WE LOVE HER VERY MUCH
AND SHE WILL BE FINE.
WE ARE DEVASTATED FOR THE REST
OF THE FAMILIES.
WE DON'T KNOW WHO WAS HURT.
I DO KNOW MY CLOSE FRIENDS'S
CHILDREN ARE OKAY, BUT WE DON'T
KNOW WHO THE CHILDREN WERE.
>> I DON'T KNOW IF SHE CAN HEAR
ME OR NOT, BUT I WONDERED IF SHE
WANTED TO SAY ANYTHING ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED TO HER TODAY.
>> DO YOU WANT TO SAY ANYTHING,
HONEY?
ARE YOU SURE?
>> SHE TOO COLD NOW.
>> SHE SHOULD PROBABLY GO HOME
WITH HER MOM.
IT'S BEEN A TERRIFYING DAY FOR
EVERYBODY INVOLVED.
I AM SO GRATEFUL THAT YOU WERE
ABLE TO SEE YOUR DAUGHTER.
OBVIOUSLY YOUR HEART MUST GO OUT
TO THE POOR FAMILIES WHO HAVE
NOT BEEN ABLE TO SEE THEIR POOR
CHILDREN AGAIN.
>> IT'S A SMALL COMMUNITY AND
IT'S A CLOSE-KNIT SCHOOL AND
DEVASTATING.
I WILL BE HERE FOR ANYBODY AND
OUR PRAYERS GO OUT TO ALL THE
FAMILIES.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH INDEED.
>> I'M JUST THE LUCKIEST LADY
RIGHT NOW.
>> THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH INDEED
FOR JOINING ME.
I APPRECIATE IT.
>> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU.
>> VERY LUCKY INDEED.
THE GUNMAN IS ADAM LANZA AND
JOINING ME IS LANZA'S FORMER
CLASSMATE, ALEX ISRAEL.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING ME.
YOU KNEW THIS CHARACTER.
IS THIS SOMETHING YOU COULD HAVE
PREDICTED HE WOULD ONE DAY FLIP
AND DO SOMETHING AS MONSTROUS AS
THIS?
>> I DON'T KNOW IF YOU CAN EVER
PREDICT SOMETHING LIKE THAT
WOULD HAPPEN.
YOU NEVER THINK IT'S GOING TO
HAPPEN TO YOUR SCHOOL AND WHERE
YOU LIVED YOUR WHOLE LIFE.
I DON'T KNOW IF I COULD PREDICT
IT.
THERE WAS SOMETHING OFF ABOUT
HIM.
I KNEW HIM CLOSELY WHEN WE WERE
VERY YOUNG IN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
TOGETHER.
HE WAS ALWAYS A LITTLE BIT
DIFFERENT.
HE MOSTLY STUCK TO HIMSELF.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU CAN SAY YOU
CAN PREDICT THIS.
>> HE WAS BY ALL ACCOUNTS A
PRETTY CLEVER YOUNG MAN, ALMOST
A GENIUS IN MATH.
TELL ME ABOUT THAT SIDE OF HIM.
>> I WAS NEVER IN ANY OF HIS
CLASSES OR ANYTHING LIKE THAT,
BUT YEAH, YOU COULD DEFINITELY
TELL HE WAS I WOULD SAY A
GENIUS.
THERE WAS DEFINITELY SOMETHING
THERE THAT WAS A LITTLE BIT
ABOVE THE REST OF US.
>> DID HE HAVE FRIENDS?
WAS HE SOCIABLE?
>> I ALWAYS SAW HIM ALONE WHEN
HE WAS WALKING THROUGH THE
SCHOOL OR SITTING AT THE TABLE,
SITTING ON THE BUS.
I'M SURE HE HAD A FEW MAYBE
CLOSE FRIENDS THROUGH SCHOOL OR
THROUGH HIS CLASSES.
MOST OF THE TIME I SAW HIM, HE
WAS ALONE.
YEAH.
>> HOW WOULD YOU DESCRIBE HIS
PERSONALITY?
>> HE WAS REALLY QUIET.
HE KEPT TO HIMSELF.
HE WAS A LITTLE FIDGETY.
A LITTLE UNEASY SOMETIMES IF YOU
WERE TO LOOK AT HIM.
I THINK HE WAS JUST SOCIALLY NOT
REALLY INTO GOING OUT THERE AND
MAKING AS MANY FRIENDS AS
EVERYONE WAS DOING IN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AND MIDDLE SCHOOL.
HE PREFERRED TO STAY TO HIMSELF.
>> DID YOU KNOW HIS FAMILY, HIS
MOTHER IN PARTICULAR?
>> I KNEW HER BECAUSE WE LIVED
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
I KNEW HER THROUGH NEIGHBORHOOD
EVENTS.
MY MOM KNEW HER.
SHE WAS A VERY NICE WOMAN.
A KINDER GARTEN TEACHER
OBVIOUSLY.
I DIDN'T KNOW HER PERSONALLY,
BUT FROM WHAT I REMEMBER, SHE
WAS A NICE WOMAN.
>> HIS PARENTS GOT DIVORCED.
WERE YOU AWARE OF THAT HAVING A
BIG IMPACT ON HIM?
>> I DON'T KNOW WHEN THEY GOT
DIVORCED.
I HAVE KNOWN HIM SINCE ABOUT
FIRST GRADE AND HE HAS ALWAYS
BEEN THE WAY I DESCRIBED HIM.
RESERVED AND QUIET.
SO I DON'T KNOW IF THE DIVORCE
HAD ANYTHING TO DO WITH THAT OR
WHEN THEY DIVORCED.
THAT COULD HAVE CAUSED THAT OR
MADE IT WORSE AS HE GOT OLDER
AND CAME MORE RESERVED.
I'M NOT SURE IF THAT AFFECTED
IT.
>> WHERE WERE YOU WHEN YOU HEARD
AND WHAT WAS YOUR IMMEDIATE
REACTION WHEN YOU DISCOVERED IT
WAS THIS PERSON YOU KNEW?
>> IT WAS DEVASTATING.
I'M IN LONDON NOW STUDYING HERE
FOR THE SEMESTER AND COMING HOME
ON THURSDAY TO THIS.
I FOUND OUT FIRST EARLY THIS
MORNING I GUESS PROBABLY WHEN IT
BROKE AT HOME.
IT WAS AROUND 2:00 AND THE FIRST
INFORMATION OF IT, IT'S
DEVASTATING IN A TOWN WHERE YOU
HAVE KNOWN UP.
I FELT SAFE MY WHOLE LIFE AND I
WAS RAISED IN THAT ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AND THE SCHOOL SYSTEM
THERE AND FINDING OUT IT WAS
SOMEONE I KNEW WHO HAD DONE ALL
OF THIS IS JUST UPSETTING.
YOU CAN'T IMAGINE THAT WOULD
EVER HAPPEN.
>> THE COMMUNITY AROUND NEWTOWN,
HOW WOULD YOU DESCRIBE IT?
I'M HEARING IT WAS A VERY QUIET
PLACE.
STUFF LIKE THIS JUST NEVER
HAPPENS.
THEY DON'T GET MANY SHOOTINGS
AND GUN MURDERS.
THIS IS AN EXCEPTIONAL KIND OF
PLACE IN THAT SENSE.
>> NO.
I MEAN IT'S A PRETTY BIG TOWN
SPACE-WISE.
WE SPAN OVER A PRETTY VAST ARRAY
OF LAND, BUT IT'S REALLY
CLOSE-KNIT IN THAT EVERYONE
KNOWS EACH OTHER AND IS CLOSE
WITH EACH OTHER AND THE SCHOOL
SYSTEMS ARE CLOSE.
YOU GROW UP WITH THESE PEOPLE
AND GO TO SCHOOL WITH THEM.
EVERYONE REALLY CAME TOGETHER, I
THINK, THROUGH THIS AND IS
SUPPORTING EACH OTHER QUITE
WELL.
THAT'S ONE GOOD THING TO COME
OUT OF IT IF ANYTHING.
>> WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME YOU
SPOKE TO ADAM LANZA?
>> PROBABLY MIDDLE SCHOOL.
I DIDN'T HAVE ANY CONNECTION
WITH HIM IN HIGH SCHOOL.
MIDDLE SCHOOL PROBABLY.
THE LAST TIME I SAID A WORD TO
HIM.
>> YOUR SUMMARY IS KIND OF
FIDGETY AND SLIGHTLY A LONER AND
NOT MASSIVELY SOCIABLE, BUT NOT
APPARENTLY DANGEROUS.
>> NO, I MEAN I NEVER NOTICED
ANYTHING SCARY OR VIOLENT OR
ANYTHING LIKE THAT.
I WOULD NEVER HAVE EXPECTED THAT
FROM HIM, I DON'T THINK.
JUST FOR SOMEONE WHO SORT OF
WENT UNDER THE RADAR AND KEPT TO
THEMSELVES, YOU WOULDN'T REALLY
THINK OF THEM AS DOING SOMETHING
CRAZY LIKE THIS.
>> IT MUST HAVE BEEN A HECK OF A
SHOCK TO YOU AND I AM GRATEFUL
FOR YOU JOINING US TO GIVE US
PERSPECTIVE ON THE CHARACTER OF
THIS PERSON.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> THE PSYCHOLOGY OF THE
SHOOTER, ADAM A LANZ IS A.
TWO EXPERTS ARE HERE TO TALK
ABOUT THE GUNMAN.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Let's talk about
low-cost investing.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
At Schwab, we're committed
to offering you
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
low-cost investment options--
like our Exchange
Traded Funds, or ETFs
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
which now have the lowest
operating expenses
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
in their respective
Lipper categories.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Lower than SPDR
and even lower than Vanguard.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
That means with Schwab,
your portfolio has
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
a better chance to grow.
And you can trade
all our ETFs online,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
commission-free, from your
Schwab account.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
So let's talk about
saving money,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
with Schwab ETFs.
Schwab ETFs now have the lowest
operating expenses
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
in their respective
Lipper categories.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Call 1-800-4SCHWAB
or visit Schwab.com
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
to open an account today.
Funding is easy
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
with Schwab Mobile Deposit.
Investors should consider
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
carefully information
D#: 1-800-345-2550
contained in the prospectus,
cluding investment objectives,
D#: 1-800-345-2550
risks, charges, and expenses.
You can obtain
D#: 1-800-345-2550
a prospectus by visiting
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
w.schwab.com/schwabetfs.
Please read the prospectus
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
carefully before investing.
>> EARLIER TODAY A NUMBER OF OUR
CITIZENS, BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN HAD
THEIR LIFE TAKEN AWAY FROM THEM,
AS WELL AS ADULTS WHOSE
RESPONSIBILITY IT WAS TO EDUCATE
AND SUPERVISE THOSE CHILDREN.
THE PERPETRATOR OF THE CRIME IS
DEAD, AS IS AN INDIVIDUAL WHO
THE PERPETRATOR LIVED WITH.
>> THE CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR
TALKING ABOUT THIS TRAGEDY.
WE HAVE NEW INFORMATION ON THE
GUNMAN.
WHAT COULD HAVE DRIVEN HIM TO DO
THIS?
LET'S START WITH YOU IF I MAY.
I HAVE BEEN INVOLVED IN MANY OF
THESE KINDS OF INCIDENTS AND
POSSIBLY NOTHING AS APPALLING AS
THIS.
THERE SEEMS TO BE A PATTERN WITH
AURORA AND THE SHOPPING MALL
SHOOTING LAST WEEK.
YOUNG MEN IN THEIR EARLY 20s
SUDDENLY FLIPPING AND GETTING
AHOLD OF WEAPONS AND CAUSING
OUTRAGES.
WHAT IS DRIVING THEM?
WHAT IS THE POSSIBLE BACKGROUND
TO WHAT IS GOING ON HERE?
>> WORKING ON A LOT OF THESE
CASES THERE A NUMBER OF
DIFFERENT CAUSES THAT CAN BE
DIVIDED INTO TWO BROAD
CATEGORIES.
ONE CATEGORY IS PEOPLE WHO HAVE
THAT TRAIT OF A LOSS OF EMPATHY
AND INABILITY TO CONNECT TO
OTHER PEOPLE AND A HISTORY OF
CRUELTY OR WHAT PEOPLE TALK
ABOUT AS SOCIOPATHS OR
ANTISOCIAL PERSONALITY.
AT THE OTHER END PEOPLE WITH
BRAIN DISORDERS AND SERIOUS
MENTAL ILLNESSES THAT ARE
UNTREATED OR BECAUSE OF WHAT'S
HAPPENING IN THEIR LIFE,
EXACERBATED BY STRESS.
IT SOUNDS LIKE THE LITTLE BIT
THAT IS COMING OUT, WE ARE MORE
IN A DIRECTION THAT THIS IS
SOMEONE WITH A BRAIN DISORDER
AND OTHER PARTS OF THE STORY
THAT IT MAY TAKE YEARS TO
UNCOVER IT.
THERE IS NOTHING SUDDEN ABOUT
ANY OF THESE STORIES.
THAT'S THE HEADLINE FOR ME.
IT'S SUDDEN FOR US THAT THIS
HAPPENED.
AS YOU BEGIN TO UNDERSTAND THE
STORY, I ASSURE YOU THE WARNING
SIGNS WERE THERE.
NOT THAT THEY WERE IGNORED, BUT
THEY WERE NOT RECOGNIZED.
>> ARE PEOPLE LIKE THIS AS
LIKELY TO CARRY OUT WHAT THEY
END UP DOING IF THEY DIDN'T HAVE
EASY ACCESS TO FIREARMS?
>> LOOK, THERE IS NO QUESTION
THAT FIREARMS PLAY A ROLE.
I CAN TELL YOU FROM EXPERIENCE
IF SOMEBODY WANTS TO KILL A
NUMBER OF PEOPLE, THERE OTHER
WEAPONS OF DESTRUCTION AND WAYS
TO MAKE BOMBS AND AT LEAST ONE
CASE I WORKED ON.
FIREARMS ARE CERTAINLY AN
IMPORTANT PART OF THE PICTURE,
BUT UNDERSTANDING WHEN SOMEBODY
HAS A MENTAL ILLNESS IF IT
IT I HAS PLAYED A ROLE HERE AND
I'M NOT SAYING THAT I KNOW THAT
IT HAS, THAT SHOULD BE
CONSIDERED BEFORE ALLOWING THAT
PERSON TO HAVE A FIREARM.
>> FRANK, YOU SPECIALIZE IN
TREATING POST TRAUMATIC STRESS
AND THE EFFECTS OF VIOLENCE.
A VERY PARTICULAR PROBLEM HERE
WITH SO MANY YOUNG PEOPLE AT THE
SCHOOL WHO HAVE LUCKILY
SURVIVED.
HAVING TO DEAL NOW WITH THE
HORROR OF LOSING POSSIBLE
FRIENDS AND PEOPLE THAT THEY
KNEW FROM THE SCHOOL AND
TEACHERS AND THE HEAD TEACHER
AND SO ON.
WHERE DO YOU START WITH TRYING
TO COUNSEL YOUNG CHILDREN WHEN
THIS KIND OF APPALLING THING
HAPPENS?
>> I THINK THE FIRST THING IS
HELPING THE PARENTS.
THE CHILDREN LOOK TO THEIR
PARENTS AND FOR THE PARENTS,
SOME OF THEM ARE STUNNED.
THEY ARE GRIEVING.
THEY LOST A PRECIOUS 6-YEAR-OLD.
FOR THE CHILDREN THEMSELVES,
SOMETIMES CHILDREN WHO GO
THROUGH THIS AND DO SURVIVE TAKE
A WHILE TO MAKE SENSE OUT OF IT.
THEY MAY REGRESS AND MOVE
BACKWARDS A YEAR OR TWO IN TERMS
OF THEIR NORMAL DEVELOPMENT.
SOME OF THEM WILL FIGURE OUT
YEARS LATER WHAT ACTUALLY
HAPPENED.
SOME ARE GOING TO DO RELATIVELY
WELL.
THEY WILL BE SADDER AND WISER IN
A WAY.
THE MOST IMPORTANT THING IS WHAT
I SEE HAPPENING RIGHT NOW.
THAT COMMUNITY IS COMING
TOGETHER.
PEOPLE ARE LOVING EACH OTHER.
THE PRESIDENT HAS COME TO REMIND
US THAT WE ARE A NATION WHO
CARES AND HE CAME AS A FATHER.
I AM A FATHER AND A GRANDFATHER.
I HAVE CALLED MY CHILDREN AND I
WANT TO KNOW HOW THEY ARE DOING
WITH THEIR CHILDREN.
AS WE COME TOGETHER, WE DO THE
BEST THAT WE CAN AT A SAD TIME
LIKE THIS.
>> I SUPPOSE THE BIG QUESTION IS
WHY WOULD THIS SHOOTER DO WHAT
HE DID?
GO TO A CLASSROOM AND MURDER SO
MANY YOUNG CHILDREN OF SUCH A
YOUNG TENDER AGE, POSSIBLY THE
CLASSROOM THAT HIS MOTHER WAS
ALREADY KILLED AT THEIR HOME.
CAN YOU TRY TO PIECE FROM YOUR
EXPERIENCE THE THOUGHT PROCESS
HERE?
WHY HE WOULD THEN HAVING KILLED
HIS MOTHER GO TO THE SCHOOL AND
DO WHAT HE DID?
>> I DON'T HAVE A CRYSTAL BALL
AND I HAVEN'T DIAGNOSED OR
ASSESSED HIM.
PEOPLE WITH MENTAL ILLNESS ARE
NOT MORE VIOLENT.
LET ME BE CRYSTAL CLEAR ABOUT
THAT.
BECAUSE THAT'S NOT THE CASE.
THAT'S NOT THE DATA THAT WE
HAVE.
IF INDEED MENTAL ILLNESS IS A
PART OF THIS, THERE IS A
PARTICULAR PATH THAT NEEDS TO BE
LOOKED AT.
ARE THEY DEPRESSED AND
SUICIDALLY DEPRESSED.
HIS ROOMMATE ALEX ISRAEL SAID HE
PREFERRED TO STAY ALONE.
A SYMPTOM OF ASPERGER'S AND
ONE REPORT COMING OUT WHICH MAY
OR MAY NOT BE TRUE.
SOMETHING IS MISSING IN THE
BRAIN.
A SENSE OF EMPATHY AND SOCIAL
CONNECTION THAT LEAVES THIS
PERSON SUFFERING FROM THIS
CONDITION.
THEY ARE PRONE TO SERIOUS
DEPRESSION AND ANXIETY.
IF THEY ARE SUICIDALLY
DEPRESSED, WE DON'T KNOW ENOUGH.
WHAT I AM TRYING TO DO IN
AGREEING TO COME HERE IS TO ASK
PEOPLE TO DON'T RUSH TO JUDGMENT
ABOUT WHO THIS YOUNG MAN IS.
IF IT WAS MENTAL ILLNESS THAT
PLAYED A ROLE, IT'S AN
OPPORTUNITY FOR US TO DO BETTER.
>> THERE IS A SCHOOL THAT YOU
SHOULDN'T GIVE HIM ATTENTION AND
NAME HIM AND SO ON BECAUSE IT
BRINGS ATTENTION TO HIM.
HE'S DEAD SO HE WON'T BE ABLE TO
BASK IN THE APPALLING GLORY OF
WHAT HE DID, BUT SECONDLY THESE
-- THERE'S A PATTEN OF THESE
YOUNG MEN.
>> YOU CAN MAKE AN ASSUMPTION
THAT WE WANTS TO BASK IN THE
GLORY OF WHAT HE DID.
I HAVE MET SHOOTERS.
I HAVE SPENT MANY HOURS WITH
PEOPLE WHO HAVE DONE SOMETHING
LIKE THAT.
THEY DON'T NECESSARILY WANT
GLORY.
THEY ARE SERIOUSLY ILL.
AND OTHERS THAT DO WANT GLORY.
SO YOU ARE RUSHING TO THE AN
INTERPRETATION ON THIS.
>> SORRY.
>> I WOULD LIKE TO ENDORSE THAT
ALSO.
I KNOW FOR THE WHOLE COUNTRY, WE
REALLY WANT TO KNOW WHY THIS
HAPPENED.
WHEN YOU ARE A PARENT YOU CAN'T
STOP THINKING ABOUT THESE
QUESTIONS THAT YOU ARE ASKING.
WE HAVE TO BE VERY CAREFUL IN
ANSWERING THEM.
WHEN YOU MENTIONED THAT WE HAD
SEVERAL SIMILAR CASES RECENTLY,
YES, THESE WERE SIMILAR IN THAT
GUNS WERE USED AND THEY WERE
SPREE KILLINGS AND MASS
KILLINGS.
I CAN TELL YOU AS A MEDICAL
DOCTOR AND PSYCHIATRIST WHO
WORKED CLOSELY ON CASES, THERE
WERE DIFFERENT MOTIVES AND
MENTALITIES.
THERE PEOPLE WHO DON'T HAVE A
CONSCIOUS.
THEY TORTURE ANIMALS.
THEY HAVE NO BASIS IN THEIR MIND
FOR EMPATHY OR SYMPATHY.
THEY LEARN HOW TO FAKE IT.
I BELIEVE ONE OF THE COLUMBINE
KILLERS FIT THAT PATTERN, BUT
THE OTHER WAS COMPLETELY
DIFFERENT.
HE WAS NOT A PSYCHOPATH.
IN THE CASE OF THE AURORA
SHOOTER, THE JURY IS NOT IN YET,
BUT I HAVE A FEELING WE WILL
FIND HE WAS ON THE VERGE OF
MAJOR MENTAL ILLNESS ABOUT
DELUSIONS AND HALLUCINATIONS.
ONE TIME IN MY LIFE I WAS
RESPONSIBLE FOR THE FEDERAL
PROGRAM OF MENTAL HEALTH
SERVICES IN AMERICA.
I HAVE TO ADMIT WE FAILED.
WE FAILED AMERICA IN PROTECTING
THE LIVES OF THE SERIOUSLY
MENTALLY ILL.
MOST OF WHAT THEY DO IS SUFFER
IN SILENCE.
THEIR FAMILIES WANT TO DO BETTER
BY THEM AND AS A COUNTRY WE HAVE
NOT STEPPED UP AND BEEN
SYMPATHETIC AND CARING AND
APPROPRIATE FOR THE SERIOUSLY
MENTALLY ILL.
>> AN EXTREMELY IMPORTANT POINT.
WHAT I WAS GOING TO SAY IS YOU
BOTH HAVE MADE EXTREMELY VALID
POINTS.
YOU HAVE THREE SUCCESSIVE
APPALLING MASS SHOOTINGS
INVOLVING YOUNG MEN IN THEIR 20s
WHERE THE BACKGROUND TO ALL OF
THEM, FROM PEOPLE THAT KNEW THEM
WAS NOT DISSIMILAR.
THEY SEEM TO BE FAIRLY NORMA
KIND OF SLIGHTLY OFF, BUT
NOTHING WITH ALARM BELLS.
THE POINT OF EXAMINING THEIR
CHARACTER IS THAT THERE MUST BE
A GOOD LIKELIHOOD THAT THERE
OTHERS LIKE THAT OUT THERE WHO
MAY BE CONSIDERING SIMILAR
ATROCITIES.
HOW DO PEOPLE WHO KNOW THESE
TYPES OF PEOPLE SPOT ANY WARNING
SIGNS?
>> PIERS --
>> LET ME START WITH THE DOCTOR.
>> I'M SORRY.
I HAVE THREE SMALL CHILDREN.
BEFORE THIS INTERVIEW THEY ASKED
ME WHAT I WAS DOING AND WE
TALKED ABOUT THIS FOR ABOUT AN
HOUR AND A HALF.
MY 9-YEAR-OLD GOT FRIGHTENED, HE
GOES TO ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
I EXPLAINED TO HIM THAT THESE
THINGS ARE EXCEEDINGLY RARE.
LET'S NOT FORGET, THIS IS
EXCEEDINGLY RARE.
JUST BECAUSE SOMETHING HAPPENED
IN THE LAST MONTH DOESN'T
STATISTICALLY MAKE IT A COMMON
OCCURRENCE.
LET'S BE CLEAR AND TELL OUR
CHILDREN THAT.
THIS IS AN OPPORTUNITY TO TURN
TRAGEDY INTO AN OPPORTUNITY TO
FIX SOME OF THE THINGS THAT ARE
TERRIBLY BROKEN IN OUR MENTAL
HEALTH CARE SYSTEM AND KNOW HOW
TO IDENTIFY PEOPLE AT RISK FOR
VIOLENCE.
IT'S ALL AT THE LEVEL OF STATE
FUNDING.
SORRY ABT GET GET INTO THE
SPECIFICS, BUT IT'S MENTAL
HEALTH CARE AND SCREENING OF NOT
ONLY YOUNG ADULTS AND CHILDREN
WHO OFFER A GOOD ASSESSMENT, WE
CAN IN FACT DO A MUCH BETTER JOB
OF NOT ONLY CARING FOR THE
PEOPLE AND IDENTIFY THOSE WHO
WOULD NEVER BE VIOLENT IF NOT
FOR A MENTAL ILLNESS.
THAT IS ONE BIT OF THE STORY.
THERE IS ANOTHER PART WHICH IS
WHAT I THINK THAT MOST PEOPLE
ARE MORE FAMILIAR WITH AND
INTERESTED IN BECAUSE OF MOVIES.
THE DIABOLICAL SOCIOPATH.
BOTH STORIES ARE TRUE, BUT BOTH
ARE ACTUALLY QUITE RARE.
>> THE FINAL WORD, MAKE IT BRIEF
IF YOU MAY.
>> AMERICA HAS MORE GUN DEATHS
THAN ANY OTHER ADVANCED NATION
IN THE WORLD.
WE HAVE LAWS THAT SAY IF YOU ARE
SERIOUSLY MENTALLY ILL, YOU
SHOULDN'T POSSESS A WEAPON AND
WE DON'T ENFORCE THE LAWS.
WE HAVE TO GET TOGETHER ACROSS
THIS DIVIDE AND NEED THE NRA TO
STEP UP AND SAY THEY BELIEVE IN
GUN SAFETY AND NOT JUST IN GUN
OWNERSHIP.
WE NEED POLITICIANS ON BOTH
SIDES OF THE AISLE TO TACKLE
THIS PROBLEM.
WE WILL HAVE MORE DEAD AMERICAN
CHILDREN.
>> THANK YOU BOTH VERY MUCH.
STILL AHEAD, WE WILL TALK TO
SURVIVORS OF ANOTHER SHOOTING,
BUT NEXT THE PUSH FOR MORE GUN
CONTROL AFTER THE TRAGEDY.
WE'LL DEBATE IT.
[ Female Announcer ]
IMAGINE SKIN SO HEALTHY,
IT NEVER GETS DRY AGAIN.
CAN YOUR MOISTURIZER DO THAT?
[ Female Announcer ]
DERMATOLOGIST RECOMMENDED
Aveeno HAS AN OAT FORMULA,
NOW PROVEN
TO BUILD A MOISTURE RESERVE,
SO SKIN CAN REPLENISH ITSELF.
THAT'S HEALTHY SKIN FOR LIFE.
ONLY FROM Aveeno.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
>>> THESE NEIGHBORHOODS ARE OUR
NEIGHBORHOODS.
THESE CHILDREN ARE OUR CHILDREN.
WE ARE GOING TO HAVE TO COMING
TO AND TAKE MEANINGFUL ACTION TO
PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS
REGARDLESS OF THE POLITICS.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA ON THE
SHOOTING.
THE MASSACRE IS RAISING NEW
QUESTIONS ABOUT THE ACCESS OF
GUNS IN AMERICA.
HE IS URGENTLY CALLING FOR MORE
GUN CONTROL.
A FORMER CHIEF ECONOMIST ON THE
SENTENCING COMMISSION ON MORE
GUNS, LESS CRIME.
DAN GROSS PRESIDENT OF THE BRADY
CLUB FOR NONVIOLENCE.
THE ATTORNEY FOR THE MICHIGAN
AND RESPONSIBLE GUN OWNERS.
LET'S START WITH YOU.
YOU WERE PRETTY OUTSPOKEN SAYING
THIS IS TIME TO BRING IN NEW GUN
CONTROL LAWS.
>> YES.
IF THIS DOESN'T WAKE US UP, I
DON'T KNOW WHAT WILL.
I WAS HEARTENED THAT THE
PRESIDENT SAID WE HAD TO TAKE
MEANINGFUL ACTION AND THE ONLY
THING HE CAN DO IS LEAD A
CRUSADE FOR REASONABLE GUN
CONTROL LEGISLATION IN CONGRESS.
THESE MASSACRES ARE TAKING PLACE
MORE AND MORE OFTEN.
WE SAW, BY THE WAY, TODAY, A
VERY SIMILAR INCIDENT IN CHINA
WHERE A MAD MAN ATTACKED AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN CHINA WITH
A KNIFE.
22 INJURED CHILDREN.
INJURED, NOT DEAD.
THAT'S THE DIFFERENCE.
IN THE UNITED STATES WE HAVE
9,000 PEOPLE KILLED WITH GUNS
LAST YEAR IN SIMILAR COUNTRIES
LIKE GERMANY, 170 AND CANADA
150.
THERE IS A REASON FOR THAT.
>> WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE TO SEE IN
TERMS OF SPECIFIC GUN CONTROL?
>> THERE A NUMBER OF PIECES OF
LEGISLATION WE HAVE BEEN
PUSHING.
NO REASONABLE GUN OWNER WHO IS A
SPORTSMAN CAN OBJECT TO BANS ON
ASSAULT WEAPONS MADE ONLY TO
KILL AS MANY HUMAN BEINGS AS
POSSIBLE LIKE IN A MILITARY
SITUATION.
NO ONE CAN OBJECT TO A BAN ON
THE SALE OF LARGE AMMUNITION
CLIPS SO YOU CAN'T RELOAD.
NO ONE CAN OBJECT TO
MICROSTAMPING OF CARTRIDGES SO
YOU CAN TRACE THE WEAPON.
NO ONE CAN REASONABLY OBJECT TO
ELIMINATING THE GUN SHOW
EXCEPTION SO THAT EVEN IF YOU
BUY A GUN AT A GUN SHOW THEY
HAVE TO CHECK YOUR BACKGROUND TO
MAKE SURE YOU ARE NOT SELLING A
GUN TO A MENTALLY UNSTABLE
PERSON, OR A FELON.
THOSE ARES WE SHOULD DO.
>> WE HAD A HEATED DEBATE ON A
PREVIOUS INCIDENT.
TWO THINGS HAPPENED IN 1996.
THERE WAS A MASSACRE IN TASMANIA
IN WHICH 35 PEOPLE WERE KILLED.
THE AUSTRALIANS WAS RIGHT WING
AND FRIENDS OF GEORGE W. BUSH
AND BROUGHT IN DRACONIAN LAWS
AFTER THAT.
HE BROUGHT IN RIFLES AND
SHOTGUNS.
AS A RESULT OF THE NEXT DECADE,
FIREARM HOMICIDE RATE FELL BY
59% AND SUICIDE RATE FELL BY
65%.
>> NOT TRUE.
>> IT IS TRUE.
>> NO, IT'S NOT.
IF YOU LOOK OVER TIME --
>> IT IS TRUE.
>> I'M TELLING YOU PEOPLE CAN
LOOK IT UP THEMSELVES.
WHAT YOU FIND IS FOR DECADES THE
MURDER RATE WAS FALLING IN
AUSTRALIA.
IT BASICALLY STOPPED FALLING.
IF YOU COMPARE THE AVERAGE O TWO
DECADES WHERE IT'S FALLING TO
WHAT IT WAS AFTERWARDS, IT MAKES
IT LOOK LIKE THE AVERAGE BEFORE
IS HIGHER THAN AFTERWARDS.
IF YOU LOOK ON A YEAR BY YEAR
BASIS, THERE WASN'T THAT FALL.
>> WHY DOES ADAM LANZA'S MOTHER
NEED TO HAVE THESE THREE
WEAPONS?
>> CAN I FOLLOW-THROUGH ON THE
AUSTRALIAIA THING?
>> NO, WHY DOES SHE NEED TO HAVE
THESE THREE WEAPONS PERFORMED
INCLUDING THIS SEMI AUTOMATIC
BUSHMASTER?
WHY WOULD A WOMAN TEACHER AT A
KINDERGARTEN NEED THESE WEAPONS
IN THEY ARE HOME?
ALLOWING THEREFORE A CLEARLY
DERANGED SON TO TAKE THEM AND
COMMIT THIS ATROCITY?
>> WHATEVER THAT GUN LOOKS LIKE,
IT'S A SEMI AUTOMATIC RIFLE.
ANY HUNTING RIFLE IS SEMI
AUTOMATIC.
DOESN'T MEAN IT FUNCTIONS
DIFFERENTLY.
>> HE FIRED OFF OVER A HUNDRED
ROUNDS IN SEVERAL MINUTES WITH
THIS APPARENTLY HARMLESS RIFLE.
>> GUNS MAKE IT EASY.
>> YOU ARE TRYING TO SAY IT'S AN
AVERAGE GUN.
HE FIRED OVER 100 ROUNDS AND
KILLED 20 CHILDREN.
20 CHILDREN BETWEEN 5 AND 10.
WHAT POINT DO YOU SAY WE GET IT?
IT'S TIME FOR CHANGE?
>> IT IS TIME.
WE HAVE LOOKED --
>> TIME TO DO WHAT?
>> TO GET RID OF THE GUN LAWS --
>> WHICH ONES?
>> LOOK AT WHAT HAS HAPPENED.
ALL OF THESE OCCUR WRD GUNS ARE
BANNED.
LOOK AT THE AURORA MOVIE THEATER
SHOOTING.
>> WHAT DOES THAT HAVE TO DO
WITH IT?
SERIOUSLY?
WHAT DOES THAT HAVE TO DO WITH
IT.
>> YOU NEVER LET ME EXPLAIN.
>> YOU THINK BECAUSE IT IS A
GUN-FREE ZONE.
>> LOOK AT THE AURORA MOVIE
THEATER FOR EXAMPLE.
SEVERAL THEATERS SHOWING THE
"BATMAN" MOVIE WITHIN A
20-MINUTE DRIVE.
ONLY ONE OF THOSE BANNED GUNS.
HE DIDN'T GO CLOSE TOAST HIS
HOME OR WITH THE LARGEST SCREEN.
HE WENT TO THE ONE MOVIE THEATER
THAT BANNED GUNS.
IF YOU LOOK AT BANS GENERALLY,
YOU CAN'T POINT TO A PLACE,
CHICAGO, D.C. WHERE WE BAN GUNS
AND MURDER RATES AND VIOLENT
CRIMES WENT UP.
IN THE UK IN JAMAICA AND
IRELAND, ISLAND NATIONS THAT
BANNED GUNS, YOU CAN'T FIND A
PLACE WHERE MURDER RATES HAVE
GONE DOWN.
THEY HAVE GONE UP USUALLY BY
LARGE AMOUNTS.
>> YOU CANNOT FIND A PLACE --
>> LET ME BRING IN.
>> FIRST OF ALL, BASICALLY EVERY
STATISTIC THAT JOHN CITED IS
PURE BUNK IN TERMS OF THE FACT
THAT THE MORE GUNS EQUAL --
THAT'S TRUE.
THEY WERE GUN-FREE ZONES, BUT
ATTRIBUTING THAT TO THE FACT
THAT THIS VIOLENCE OCCURRED,
THAT'S WHERE I HAVE TO STEP IN.
LISTEN, MY BROTHER WAS SHOT IN A
SHOOTING ON TOP OF THE EMPIRE
STATE BUILDING WHICH WAS
CHAOTIC.
I KNOW FIRSTHAND.
I TALKED WITH THE VICTIMS FROM
THE AURORA TRAGEDY.
TO A PERSON, THEY ALL SAY IF
THERE WERE ANOTHER PERSON ARMED,
IT WOULD HAVE LED TO MORE
CARNAGE.
EXCUSE ME.
I LET YOU TALK, LET ME FINISH.
LET ME FINISH.
IN EVERY ONE OF THE CASES THEY
SAY IF THERE WERE MORE GUNS, IT
WOULD HAVE ONLY LED TO MORE
CHAOS.
AT THE EMPIRE BUILDING SHOOTING
IN NEW YORK.
THERE WERE HIGHLY TRAINED
LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICERS IN THE
CHAOS.
THERE WERE EIGHT OTHER PEOPLE
SHOT AND EVERY ONE WAS AN
INNOCENT CIVILIAN AND EVERY ONE
WAS SHOT BY THESE LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICERS.
>> WE HAVE THE ATTORNEY FOR THE
RESPONSIBLE GUN OWNERS.
YOU BELIEVE THAT THERE SHOULD BE
MORE GUNS IN SCHOOLS.
IS THAT RIGHT?
>> I BELIEVE THOSE OF US WHO ARE
LICENSED TO CARRY ARE
RESPONSIBLE PEOPLE AND SHOULDN'T
BE PROHIBITED FROM CARRYING IN
SCHOOLS OR OTHER PLACES.
IN FACT, THE MICHIGAN
LEGISLATURE PASSED A BILL LAST
NIGHT AND SENT TO THE GOVERNOR
FOR SIGNATURE A BILLE THAT WILL
ALLOW THOSE WHO ARE LICENSED TO
TAKE ONE MORE DAY OF TRAINING
INCLUDING RANGE TIME AND CARRY
IN PLACES WHERE WE COULDN'T
CARRY BEFORE.
>> WHY ON EARTH WOULD YOU WANT
MORE GUNS IN SCHOOLS AFTER WHAT
HAPPENED TODAY?
>> HERE'S WHY, PIERS.
IF WE COULD SUDDENLY MAKE ALL
GUNS DISAPPEAR, I WOULD HAVE A
DIFFERENT POSITION.
I SPEND A LOT OF TIME THINKING
ABOUT THIS AND READING ABOUT
IT.
I TEACH A CLASS AT THE LAW
SCHOOL LEVEL CALLED GUN CONTROL
SEMINAR.
AND I GET A NEW GROUP EVERY TIME
AND WE DISCUSS IT IN DETAIL.
THE SIMPLE FACTS ARE GUNS EXIST.
THEY ARE ESSENTIALLY 1800s
TECHNOLOGY.
SEMI AUTOMOBILES WERE IN THE
LATE 1800s.
THEY ARE EASY TO MAKE AND LAST
SEVERAL HUMAN LIFETIMES WITH
MINIMAL MAINTENANCE.
SINCE GUNS EXIST AND WE KNOW FOR
A FACT THAT THE ONLY WAY TO STOP
AN EVIL PERSON, LIKE THE PERSON
YOU WERE DISCUSSING EARLIER IN
THE SHOW IS TO --
>> THIS IS EXACTLY THE ARGUMENT
I HAVE BEEN HEARING EVER SINCE I
JOINED CNN.
I JOINED ON AIR ABOUT A WEEK
AFTER GABBY GIFFORDS THE
CONGRESSWOMAN WAS SHOT IN THE
HEAD.
EVER SINCE THEN, WE HAVE THE
SIKH TEMPLE AND AURORA AND THE
SHOPPING MALL AND SO ON AND SO
ON.
A GUY DOWNSTAIRS SHOT IN THE
HEAD FROM OUR NEW YORK BUREAU
ARE.
THE ARGUMENT I KEEP HEARING IF
EVERYBODY WAS WAS ARMED, IT
WOULDN'T HAPPEN.
IT'S A LOAD OF TOTAL HOGWASH,
ISN'T IT?
IF EVERYONE IN THAT MOVIE
THEATER HAD GUNS, MORE PEOPLE
WOULD HAVE BEEN KILLED IN THE
MAYHEM THAT ERUPTED.
>> THE PEOPLE THAT STOPPED THE
ATTACKS.
>>> CAN I JUST --
>> THE PROVE IN THE PUDDING.
YOU DON'T SEE OTHER SHOOTINGS AT
GUN SHOWS OR --
>> YOU CAN'T GIVE ME ONE EXAMPLE
WHERE BYSTANDERS WERE HIT IN THE
EMPIRE STATE BUILDING.
>> PROOF IS MANY THE BUILDING.
>> YOU DON'T SEE MASS SHOOTINGS
AT GUN SHOWS OR SHOOTING RANGES.
>> THEY HAVE REASONABLE GUN
CONTROL LAWS AND THEY HAVE A
HUNDRED PEOPLE A YEAR NOT 9,000
OR
10,000 A YEAR.
>> LISTEN --
>> IT WAS LOWER BEFORE GUN
CONTROL.
>> THEY GOT THE GUN CONTROL.
>> ALMOST ZERO CRIME.
>> THE GUN CONTROL DOESN'T
CHANGE IT.
>> SCOTLAND IN 1996 THERE WAS A
SIMILAR SCHOOL SHOOTING.
JUST AN AWFUL SITUATION.
16 YOUNG CHILDREN KILLED EXACTLY
AS THEY WERE TODAY.
AS A RESULT OF THIS, THEY
BROUGHT IN A HAND GUN BAN.
162,000 HAND GUNS WERE HANDED
IN.
IT IS TIME FOR THIS.
>> LISTEN --
>> MURDER RATES WENT UP.
>> THERE ABOUT 35 MURDERS A
YEAR.
THERE 12,000 MURDERS A YEAR FROM
GUNS IN THIS COUNTRY.
>> THE POINT IS --
>> WHEN ARE YOU GOING TO FOCUS
ON THAT AND STOP TELLING ME THE
ANSWER IS MORE GUNS.
IT'S NOT THE ANSWER.
>> LISTEN, LISTEN, LISTEN.
>> AFTER THE BAN IT WAS HIGHER
THAN BEFORE THE BAN.
>> YOU WANT MORE GUNS, NOT LESS.
300 MILLION GUNS IN AMERICA
ISN'T ENOUGH FOR YOU?
>> WHEN YOU BAN GUNS --
>> HOW MANY KIDS HAVE TO DIE
BEFORE YOU SAY WE WANT LESS
GUNS, NOT MORE.
>> I WANT TO TELL YOU
SOMETHING --
>> LET MINIMUM ANSWER THE
QUESTION.
>> I'M UPSET BECAUSE I'M WORRIED
THE GUN CONTROL LAWS YOU ARE
PUSH HAVING KILLED PEOPLE.
>> WHAT A LOAD OF NONSENSE.
>> YOU HAVE TO EXPLAIN.
>> AVERAGE OF 35 KILLINGS WITH
GUNS IN A BRITAIN A YEAR.
IN HERE, NO BAN ON GUNS AND
12,000 PEOPLE A YEAR DIE FROM
GUN MURDERS.
>> THE DIFFERENCE --
>> YOU HAVE TO UNDERSTAND.
>> MY I HAVE THE TUNE TO SAY
SOMETHING WITHOUT SCREAMING?
>> I HAVE BEEN DEBATING THIS ALL
WEEK, FOLLOWING THE BOB COSTAS
THING, I HAVE BEEN DEBATING IT
MONTHS IF NOT YEARS.
I'M SO FRUSTRATED AND FURIOUS
THAT THESE KIDS HAVE BEEN BLOWN
AWAY AGAIN WITH LEGALLY ACQUIRED
WEAPONS.
BOY WHO'S GOT PROBLEMS TAKE HIS
MOTHERS THREE WEAPONENS
INCLUDING THIS RIDICULOUS
ASSAULT RIFLE AND WALKS IN TO
SCHOOL AND YOU GUYS WANT TO TELL
ME THE ANSWER IS MORE GUNS.
IT IS MADNESS.
>> HOW CAN YOU STOP SOMEBODY
FROM SHOOTING PEOPLE?
>> LET THE CONGRESSMAN SPEAK.
>> WHAT I WOULD BE MOST ANGRY
ABOUT IS THAT EVERY POLL SHOWS
BY MASSIVE MAJORITIES AMERICANS
AGREE WITH WHAT YOU JUST SAID.
AND YET WE HAVE A LOBBY, THE
LEADERSHIP OF THE NRA WHO
FUNCTION AS ENABLERS OF MASS
MURDERERS, THEY ARE ENABLERS OF
MASS MURDER BECAUSE THEY
TERRIFIED THE CLASS OF PEOPLE
AND EVEN THOUGH.
>> ABSOLUTE SLI NOT.
>> POLLING SHOWS MOST NRA
MEMBERS WILL OPPOSE REASONABLE
GUN CONTROLS BUT THEY LIE AND
SAY THEY WILL TAKE AWAY YOUR
GUNS AND TAKE YOUR GUNS AWAY.
>> NO ONE OUTSIDE OF A POLICE
OFFICER OR MILITARY NEEDS ONE OF
THESE IN THEIR HOUSE.
NOBODY.
>> WE NEED TO SAY SOMETHING.
>> LISTEN, THE ENCOURAGING THING
AND WHAT YOU SHOULD TAKE
INSPIRATION BECAUSE WE ARE ALL
FRUSTRATED AND OUTRAGED.
THIS CONVERSATION DOES NOT
REPRESENT WHAT THE AMERICAN
PUBLIC.
WANTS.
IT DOES NOT REPRESENT THE
CONVERSATION THAT AMERICAN
PUBLIC WANTS TO HAVE.
WE ARE IN FAVOR OF BACKGROUND
CHECKS.
74% OF NRA MEMBERS ARE AND MOST
GUN SALES DO NOT REQUIRE A
BACKGROUND CHECK.
THINGS THAT WE CAN DO.
>> IT'S NOT AS THEY TRY TO TELL
ME AN ANTI-AMERICAN THING TO SAY
I RESPECT THE SECOND AMENDMENT
AND I RESPECT THE RIGHT FOR A
FAMILY TO DEFEND THEMSELVES.
I DON'T RESPECT FAMILIES TO LOAD
THEIR HOMES WITH THESE SO A
DISTURBED KID CAN TAKE THEM.
WE ARE ENDING THE DEBATE FOR
NOW.
>> WE ARE ENDING THE DEBATE FOR
NOW BUT THIS WILL CONTINUE NEXT
WEEK.
I GUARANTEE IT.
>> COME BACK NEXT WEEK WHEN YOU
HAVE HAD TIME TO THINK ABOUT
THIS BECAUSE YOU HAVE TO CHANGE
YOUR THINKING.
THE GUN LOBBY HAS TO CHANGE ITS
THINKING.
WE WILL LEAVE IT THERE.
COMING UP NEXT, SURVIVORS FROM
OTHER MASS SHOOTINGS SHARE THEIR
THOUGHTS ON TODAY'S APPALLING
MASSACRE.
A SIMILAR PICTURE FROM ANOTHER
MASS SHOOTING IN '9959 A JEWISH
COMMUNITY CENTER?
CALIFORNIA.
A 6-YEAR-OLD WAS SHOT IN THE LEG
AND I AM JOINED BY MINDY FINKLE
STEIN.
WELCOME TO YOU ALL.
LET ME START, IF I MAY, WITH
YOU.
THIS MUST HAVE BROUGHT BACK
AWFUL MEMORIES FOR YOU, AS I
DOES WHENEVER THERE IS A MASS
SHOOTING IN AMERICA.
WHAT WERER YOUR FEELINGS?
>> IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO PUT WORDS
TO WHAT I REALLY FEEL.
IT'S A MIXTURE OF SYMPATHY AND
DISGUST.
MY HEART GOES OUT TO THOSE
FAMILIES.
AND THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO HAVE
GONE THROUGH THE SAME THING AND
WHO UNDERSTAND WHAT THEY ARE
GOING THROUGH.
IMMEDIATELY WHAT I THOUGHT IS I
WISH THERE WAS SOMETHING I COULD
DO TO HELP THEM.
IN REALITY, IT'S A HELPLESS
SITUATION.
>> MINDY, YOU SURVIVED WHAT
HAPPENED TO YOU.
WHEN YOU HEAR THE RAGING GUN
DEBATES, WHICH I'M SURE WILL BE
PARTICULARLY VOCIFEROUS IN LIGHT
OF THE APPALLING INCIDENT TODAY,
DO YOU WISH AFTER WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOU AND JOSH THAT TOUGHER
LAWS HAD BEEN BROUGHT IN AFTER
THAT TO TRY TO DO SOMETHING
ABOUT THIS?
>> YOU KNOW, I DO.
I THINK THAT JOSH AND I, AND
EVERYONE IN OUR COMMUNITY IN
THIS WEIRD FAMILY THAT WE HAVE
OF SURVIVORS OF GUN LAWS WISHES
THE DAY AFTER WHAT HAPPENED TO
THEM NOBODY ELSE HAS TO GO
THROUGH IT AND UNFORTUNATELY
13 1/2 YEARS LATER WE ARE
SITTING HERE WATCHING THESE
TRAGEDIES UNFOLD ON A DAILY
BASIS YOU WERE I THINK 16 AT THE
TIME OF THE SHOOTING.
OBVIOUSLY A LOT OF THE KIDS AT
THE SCHOOL TODAY WILL BE MUCH
YOUNGER THAN THAT AND THEY WILL
HAVE LOST FRIENDS OR PEOPLE THEY
KNEW AT THE SCHOOL.
IT WILL BE VERY DIFFICULT WHEN
THEY HAVE TO GO BACK.
WHAT ADVICE WOULD YOU GIVE THEM?
WHAT IS THE BEST WAY TO DEAL
WITH THIS?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
>> YOU KNOW, TO BE HONEST, IT'S
HEART BREAKING BECAUSE THEY ARE
NOT GOING TO KNOW REALLY WHAT,
OR HOW TO FEEL UNTIL FIVE, TEN
YEARS FROM NOW WHEN IT KEEPS
HAUNTING THEM AND NIGHTMARES AND
FEARS THAT KEEP COMING UP.
JOSH CAN SPEAK TO THAT HIMSELF.
HE WAS 6 YEARS OLD AT THE TIME
AND NOW HE'S IN HIS 20s AND IT
HAUNTS HIM EVERY DAY.
I WAS 16.
I KNEW WHY I WAS SHOT AND I KNEW
SOMEBODY TRIED TO KILL ME AND
EVERY DAY, I'M ALMOST 30 YEARS
OLD, I'M HAUNTED.
THERE'S NOTHING I CAN SAY TO
THEM EXCEPT I'M SO, SO SORRY
THEY HAVE TO GO THROUGH THIS.
I REALLY TRULY HOPE THAT
SOMETHING WILL BE DONE AFTER
TODAY BECAUSE WE CANNOT STAND
FOR THIS ANYMORE.
>> STEVEN, YOU SURVIVED THE
AURORA MASSACRE.
THAT WAS JUST A FEW MONTHS AGO.
THERE WAS A HUGE OUTCRY THEN AND
PEOPLE PROMISED TO DO ALL SORTS
OF THINGS.
POLITICIAN MOUTHS, ABSOLUTELY
NOTHING HAPPENED.
AND HERE WE ARE WITH A WORSE
TRAGEDY, EVEN MORE DEAD AND THIS
TIME 20 YOUNG KIDS.
WHAT ARE YOUR VIEWS ON THE
DEBATE THAT WILL NOW UNFOLD IN
THIS?
>> I THINK THE PRESIDENT SAID
THAT WE NEED A MEANINGFUL ACTION
NOW.
HE SAID THAT IN THE PAST, SO,
I'LL BE WAITING FOR THAT ACTION.
IT'S A SHAME THAT 20 CHILDREN
HAVE TO BE SLAIN FOR US TO EVEN
START TO TALK ABOUT THIS.
I REALLY THINK THE AMERICAN
PUBLIC IS FED UP WITH THE LACK
OF CONVERSATION ON THIS ISSUE.
>> THERE HAVE BEEN MORE MASS
SHOOTINGS IN THE LAST FIVE OR
SIX YEARS THAN I THINK THE
PREVIOUS FOUR DECADES IN TERMS
OF THESE PARTICULARLY APPALLING
ONES AN YOU KEEP BEING TOLD IT
IS NOT AS BAD AS IT SEEMS, THE
SITUATION BUT IT TRULY IS.
SINCE I HAVE BEEN HERE I HAVE
BEEN UTTERLY HORRIFIED.
THAT'S WHY I GET SO ANIMATED
WHEN I DEBATE THIS ON THE SHOW
BECAUSE I COME FROM A COUNTRY
WHERE THIS WOULD BE UNTHINKING,
SHOPPING MALLS, KINDERGARTEN
CLASSROOMS COULD BE SHOT DOWN ON
AN ALMOST BIMONTHLY BASIS.
I DON'T KNOW WHY AMERICANS
AREN'T FAR MORE ANGRY.
>> IT'S ONE THING FOR
POLITICIANS TO TAKE ACTION.
IT'S EQUALLY IMPORTANT THAT THE
AMERICAN PUBLIC DEMANDS THESE
REFORMS, THESE CHANGES.
THE POLLING IS CLEAR.
THERE'S SUPPORT FOR COMMON SENSE
GUN REFORM.
82% OF GUN OWNERS SUPPORT
UNIVERSAL BACKGROUND CHECKS.
IT'S A FAILURE OF THE SYSTEM WE
HAVEN'T ARRIVED AT THAT POINT
YET.
>> PAULA, YOUR BROTHER WAS
KILLED IN THE EMPIRE STATE
BUILDING.
WHEN WE TALKED BEFORE YOU
BELIEVED TO VE RIGHT TO HAVE A
HANDGUN AND A REFERENDUM WASN'T
NEEDED.
WHAT DO YOU FEEL TODAY?
>> THE WAKE OF TODAY, A
REFERENDUM ON GUNS IS NEEDED.
I WAS TALKING THE DAY MY BROTHER
WAS MURDERED.
AS A FATHER, WITH INNOCENT
CHILDREN, I SEE THE HEART BREAK.
WE HAVE TO GO BACK TO THAT.
WE HAVE 26 FAMILIES THAT ARE
DEVASTATED RIGHT NOW.
THIS IS A DEBATE ABOUT GUN
CONTROL AND MENTAL ILLNESS.
IT IS A COMBINATION.
>> INCLUDING VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES
AND VIOLENT HOLLYWOOD MOVIES.
THE GUN VIOLENT CULTURE IN
AMERICA HAS TO BE TACKLED.
ALL AREAS.
THERE'S GOT TO BE A PROPER
DEBATE.
MY ARGUMENT IS THE POLITICIANS
DON'T WANT TO HAVE THIS DEBATE.
>> THEY HAVE TO.
THEY HAVE TO.
YOU HAVE TO HAVE A CONGRESSMAN
LIKE JERRY NADLER, A REPUBLICAN
CONGRESSMAN STEP UP AND GET
TOGETHER.
THIS HAS TO BE TAKEN