>>> ALL THATHS HAPPENED IN THE
PAST TWO DAYS IS ENOUGH TO MAKE
YOU SHAKE YOUR HEAD AND STARE AT
THE TELEVISION AND WONDER WHAT
HAPPENED TO THIS WORLD.
WE WANT TO END THIS HOUR WITH
THE REMINDER THAT THERE ARE GOOD
PEOPLE AND POSITIVE ACTS OF
KINDNESS THAT ARE HAPPENING
EVERYWHERE.
REMEMBER THIS, LAST MONTH THE
NEW YORK CITY POLICE OFFICER
OFFERED A HOMELESS MAN A PAIR OF
BOOTS ON A COLD NIGHT.
OR A TENNESSEE BOY WHO HELPED
HIS BROTHER COMPLETE IN A
TRIATHLON AND WHO COULD FORGET
THIS LIBYAN CHILD WHO DOESN'T
BELIEVE IN HATE HOLDING A SIGN
APOLOGIZING FOR THE EMBASSY
ATTACK IN BENGHAZI.
SO MUCH TO BE THANKFUL FOR EVEN
IN THIS VERY DIFFICULT TIME.
WE CONTINUE OUR COVERAGE OF THE
CONNECTICUT ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
SHOOTING RIGHT NOW.
>>> GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE.
I'M JOHN BERMAN.
WE'RE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
THIS MORNING.
>> I'M KATE BOLDUAN.
YOU'RE WATCHING OUR CONTINUING
COVERAGE.
IT FEELS LIKE WE'VE BEEN HERE A
LONG TIME JUST TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT WHAT'S GOING ON WITH THE
STORY.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL BE COMING
HERE LATER TODAY AND MEET WITH
SOME OF THE VICTIMS' FAMILIES
AND WE'RE TOLD HE WILL SPEAK AT
A VIGIL BEING HELD TONIGHT.
MEANWHILE, THE COMMUNITY IS
GRIEVING.
WE SAW MORE VIGILS HERE LAST
NIGHT REALLY MOVING VIGILS.
20 CHILDREN AND 6 ADULTS DIED IN
FRIDAY'S SHOOTING INSIDE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY.
WE SHOULD BEGIN HEARING THE
FIRST FUNERAL PLANS FOR SOME OF
THE VICTIMS VERY SOON.
WE ALSO WANT TO PASS THIS ALONG.
THE UNITED WAY HAS SET UP A
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL FUND.
DONATIONS, AS YOU CAN SEE RIGHT
THERE ON YOUR SCREEN, DONATIONS
SENT TO THE NEWTOWN SAVINGS BANK
39 MAIN STREET RIGHT HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THIS FUND WILL BE USED TO HELP
PAY FOR THE FUNERALS OF THE
VICTIMS, JOHN.
>>> POLICE SAY THEY HAVE FOUND
IMPORTANT EVIDENCE DURING THEIR
SEARCHES AT THE SCHOOL AND AT
THE SHOOTER'S HOME.
WE ALSO KNOW NOW MORE ABOUT THE
ACTUAL SHOOTING AND WHAT WEAPONS
WERE USED IN IT.
CNN NATIONAL CORRESPONDENT SUSAN
CANDIOTTI JOINS ME NOW AND,
SUSAN, WHAT ARE WE LEARNING THIS
MORNING?
>> HI, JOHN.
WELL, WE KNOW ONE THING AND THAT
IS THAT FEDERAL AGENTS AND OTHER
INVESTIGATORS WHO WILL BE BACK
OUT POUNDING OUT THE STREETS
TODAY, CHASING DOWN LEADS,
INFORMATION THEY HAVE THAT THE
SUSPECTED SHOOTER IN THIS CASE
MAY HAVE VISITED GUN STORES OR
GUN RANGES IN THE DAYS BEFORE
THE ATTACK.
HOWEVER, SO FAR OUR SOURCES TELL
US THAT THOSE TIPS HAVE NOT
PANNED OUT.
WE ALSO KNOW THAT THREE
ADDITIONAL GUNS HAVE BEEN FOUND,
ACCORDING TO OUR SOURCES, AT THE
HOME THAT THE SHOOTER SHARED
WITH HIS MOTHER.
WE'RE STANDING DOWN THE STREET
FROM THAT HOUSE RIGHT NOW.
WE ARE TOLD THAT ONE OF THOSE
THREE WEAPONS, WHICH ARE ALL
DESCRIBED TO ME AS OLDER MODEL
RIFLES, AT LEAST ONE OF THEM
HAVE BEEN TRACED TO THE MOTHER.
THEY'RE STILL CONDUCTING
ADDITIONAL TRACES.
AND WE ALSO KNOW ABOUT THOSE
THREE GUNS THAT WERE FOUND AT
THE CRIME SCENE.
TWO HANDGUNS AND A LONG GUN,
KNOWN AS A BUSHMASTER, THAT'S A
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE.
AND WE ALSO KNOW THAT
INVESTIGATORS KNOW HE USED ONE
OF THOSE GUNS.
IDENTIFIED WHICH ONE HE USED TO
KILL HIMSELF, BUT THEY'RE NOT
REVEALING WHICH ONE THAT IS.
THE LONG GUN IS THE ONE THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER SAID WAS USED
TO KILL SEVERAL VICTIMS WITH
MULTIPLE GUNSHOTS.
>> ALL THE WOUNDS THAT I KNOW OF
AT THIS POINT WERE CAUSED BY THE
LONG WEAPON.
>> THE RIFLE WAS THE PRIMARY
WEAPON?
>> YES.
I BELIEVE EVERYBODY WAS HIT MORE
THAN ONCE.
EVERYBODY'S DEATH WAS CAUSED BY,
EVERYONE THAT WE HAVE COMPLETED
SO FAR WAS CAUSED BY GUNSHOT
WOUNDS.
AND, OBVIOUSLY, THE MANNER OF
DEATH ON ALL THESE CASES HAS
BEEN CLASSIFIED AS HOMICIDE.
>> CERTAINLY FROM THAT
DESCRIPTION, IT'S HARD TO
UNDERSTAND, JOHN.
I'M SURE YOU'D AGREE WHAT THAT
SCENE MUST HAVE BEEN LIKE AND
WHY WAS EACH VICTIM SHOT
MULTIPLE TIMES.
PERHAPS WE'LL GET SOME ANSWERS
ONE DAY.
>> I SIMPLY CANNOT IMAGINE THAT
SCENE.
INVESTIGATORS, OBVIOUSLY,
FOLLOWING SO MANY LEADS NOW.
THEY WERE TALKING TO ADAM
LANZA'S FATHER AND ALSO HIS
BROTHER, I WAS IN HOBOKEN, NEW
JERSEY, FRIDAY NIGHT BECAUSE
POLICE HAD TAKEN IN HIS BROTHER,
RYAN LANZA, FOR QUESTIONING.
THAT WAS A CURIOUS THING AS IT
WAS HAPPENING.
WHAT ARE WE HEARING AT THIS
POINT FROM THEM?
DO WE KNOW?
>> THE OLDER BROTHER HAS NOT
ISSUED A STATEMENT ON HIS OWN AS
OF YET.
WE KNOW HE WAS QUESTIONED, AS
YOU SAID.
THIS IS WHAT WE KNOW, ACCORDING
TO OUR SOURCES.
THAT HE TOLD INVESTIGATORS THAT
HIS YOUNGER BROTHER HAD AUTISM.
THAT'S ALL WE KNOW.
BUT CERTAINLY, THAT'S NOT AN
EXPLANATION.
NO ONE IS SAYING THAT IT IS OR
EVEN PROVIDING ANY KIND OF A
MOTIVE OR CONNECTION TO WHAT
HAPPENED HERE.
OF COURSE, AUTHORITIES ARE
LOOKING AT EVERYTHING AS THEY
LOOK AT PROFILES.
BUT WE ALSO, AS YOU INDICATED,
HAVE HEARD NOW, WE GOT A
STATEMENT LAST NIGHT FROM THE
SUSPECT'S FATHER AND HE ISSUED
THIS STATEMENT WHICH READS IN
PART, "OUR FAMILY IS GRIEVING
ALONG WITH ALL THOSE WHO HAVE
BEEN AFFECTED BY THIS ENORMOUS
TRAGEDY.
WE ARE IN A STATE OF DISBELIEF
AND TRYING TO FIND WHATEVER
ANSWERS WE CAN.
WE, TOO, ARE ASKING WHY."
THOSE ANSWERS SEEM TO BE, JOHN,
IN SHORT SUPPLY.
>> ALL RIGHT, SUSAN CANDIOTTI,
THANK YOU SO MUCH, COVERING THIS
INVESTIGATION RIGHT FROM THE
VERY BEGINNING.
THANK YOU, SUSAN.
>>> AS WE CONTINUE OUR SPECIAL
COVERAGE HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AGAIN, WE WANT TO
WELCOME OUR VIEWERS HERE IN THE
UNITED STATES AND OUR
INTERNATIONAL VIEWERS, AS WELL,
WHO ARE JUST JOINING US RIGHT
NOW.
NEWTOWN IS MOURNING.
THERE IS NO QUESTION ABOUT THAT.
THE ENTIRE NATION IS REELING
FROM WHAT IS HAPPENING HERE.
PEOPLE GATHERING IN VIGILS AND
SERVICES TO FIND SOME SORT OF
COMFORT AND PAY TRIBUTE TO THOSE
WHO LOST THEIR LIVES ALL TOO
SOON.
WE'LL BRING YOU SOME OF THOSE
IMAGES AND SHOW YOU THE NAMES
AND AGES OF THE 20 CHILDREN AND
6 ADULTS WHO DIED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
♪
>> JUST A TRAGIC, TRAGIC
SITUATION FOR THE TEACHERS, THE
PRINCIPALS AND THOSE ANGELS.
THAT'S ALL I CAN THINK ABOUT ARE
THOSE ANGELS.
♪
>> I MEAN, WHEN THINGS HAPPEN TO
YOUR CHILDREN AND TO OTHER
PEOPLE'S CHILDREN.
I CAN'T LOOK AT MY CHILDREN'S
FACES NOW WITHOUT SEEING THE
FACES OF EVERY ONE OF THEIR
SCHOOLMATES.
♪
>> SO UNBELIEVABLY SAD.
THOSE IMAGES SO, SO UNBELIEVABLY
POWERFUL.
FOR MORE INFORMATION ON HOW YOU
CAN HELP THOSE AFFECTED BY THIS
SHOOTING, YOU CAN GO TO
CNN.COM/IMPACT.
THE HOLIDAYS ARE HERE
AND WE'RE HERE WITH CYREETA
TALKING ABOUT THE WALMART
LOW PRICE GUARANTEE.
THAT'S YOUR RECEIPT
FROM ANOTHER STORE?
IT IS!
LET'S PUT IT TO THE TEST.
ALRIGHT!
THAT'S WALMART'S
EVERYDAY LOW PRICE.
GET OUT!
OK, BUT I'M TAKING THESE!
READY?
YES.
THERE YOU HAVE IT!
THAT MUCH?
THAT'S THE WALMART
LOW PRICE GUARANTEE.
SEE FOR YOURSELF.
BRING IN YOUR LAST RECEIPT
AND SEE HOW MUCH
YOU CAN SAVE.
BE READY. WITH THE SEASON'S
TASTIEST BRANDS.
LIKE NESTLE TOLL HOUSE MORSELS.
BAKE THE VERY BEST THIS SEASON.
WALMART HAS EVERYTHING YOU NEED
TO BE READY FOR HOLIDAY HOSTING.
WITH OUR LOW PRICE GUARANTEE
BACKED BY AD MATCH.
WALMART.
CAMPBELL'S HAS 24 NEW SOUPS
THAT WILL MAKE IT DROP OVER,
AND OVER AGAIN.
♪
FROM JAMMIN' JERK CHICKEN,
TO CREAMY GOUDA BISQUE.
SEE WHAT'S NEW FROM CAMPBELL'S.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
ANY TREE ON THIS LOT
IS ON ME.
I'M THE MESSENGER,
BY THE WAY.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
JOANNE.
WITH THE HUNDREDS THAT I SAVE
WITH PROGRESSIVE
ON MY CAR INSURANCE,
THIS TREE IS ON ME.
NO WAY.
WAY.
THIS TREE IS ON ME.
REALLY?!
YES.
AAH!
LET ME JUST TRIM IT UP
A LITTLE BIT FOR YOU.
[ buzzing ]
THANK YOU.
SAVING'S GREETINGS.
YOU GUYS ARE GONNA GET THIS TREE
RIGHT HERE?
ARE YOU SURE
THAT'S THE ONE?
I'LL TIE IT TO THE ROOF
FOR YOU.
MAKE SAVINGS
A NEW HOLIDAY TRADITION.
♪
WE DON'T LET FREQUENT HEARTBURN
COME BETWEEN US
AND WHAT WE LOVE.
SO IF YOU'RE ONE OF THEM PEOPLE
WHO GETS HEARTBURN
AND THEN TREATS DAY AFTER DAY...
BLOCK THE ACID WITH PRILOSEC OTC
AND DON'T GET HEARTBURN
IN THE FIRST PLACE!
[ Male Announcer ]
ONE PILL EACH MORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBURN.
>>> I'M VICTOR BLACKWELL AT CNN
WORLD HEADQUARTERS IN ATLANTA.
HERE ARE SOME OF THE THINGS
HAPPENING THIS MORNING THAT
WE'RE FOLLOWING.
JUST 16 DAYS BEFORE THE U.S.
COULD HIT THE FISCAL CLIFF, NOW,
IN WASHINGTON, THERE COULD BE A
DEAL.
AT LEAST THEY'RE CLOSE TO A
DEAL, POSSIBLY.
A SOURCE CLOSE TO THE TALKS
TELLS CNN THAT HOUSE SPEAKER
JOHN BOEHNER IS WILLING TO HIKE
TAXES ON THE WEALTHIEST
AMERICANS.
THAT'S SOMETHING THE PRESIDENT
SAYS MUST BE INCLUDED IN ANY
PLAN, BUT SPEAKER BOEHNER
PREVIOUSLY CALLED TAX INCREASES
ON TOP EARNERS A NONSTARTER.
HIS OFFICE SAYS THERE IS NO
DEAL.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA SEEMS SET TO
NOMINATE JOHN KERRY AS HIS NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE.
UNITED NATIONS AMBASSADOR SUSAN
RICE WAS THE EXPEXED CHOICE, BUT
YOU REMEMBER SHE PULLED HER NAME
OUT OF THE RUNNING BECAUSE OF
THE CONTROVERSY OVER HER
COMMENTS IN THE WAKE OF THE
BENGHAZI ATTACKS.
THE FORMAL ANNOUNCEMENT COULD
COME THIS WEEK.
>>> OUTGOING SECRETARY OF STATE,
HILLARY CLINTON, IS RESTING AT
HOME AFTER SUFFERING A
CONCUSSION.
SHE HAS BEEN BATTLING A STOMACH
VIRUS AND FAINTED.
HER OFFICE SAID IT'S NOT SEVERE,
BUT CLINTON WILL BE FORCED TO
SKIP HER APPEARANCE IN FRONT OF
THE HOUSE FOREIGN RELATIONS
COMMITTEE THIS WEEK.
SHE WAS EXPECTED TO TESTIFY ON
THURSDAY ABOUT THE ATTACK IN
BENGHAZI, LIBYA, ON SEPTEMBER
11th.
>>> NO CHILD SHOULD EVER HAVE TO
GO THROUGH WHAT THE CHILDREN AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
WENT THROUGH.
AND NOW THE CHILDREN WHO
SURVIVED THAT MUST GET THROUGH
THE DAYS AHEAD WITH WHAT THEY'VE
ENDUR
ENDURED.
A LOT OF US ARE HAVING DIFFICULT
CONVERSATIONS WITH OUR CHILDREN,
WITH OUR FRAMILIES AND WE'RE
HAVING CONFLICTED FEELINGS.
I WANT TO BRING IN ERIC FISHER
TO TALK ABOUT THIS.
WE TALKED DURING THE BREAK AND
WE TALKED A LOT ABOUT HOW TO
SPEAK TO THE KIDS.
BUT BEFORE WE GO TO KIDS, A LOT
OF ADULTS WHO ARE HAVING A
REALLY DIFFICULT TIME COMING TO
TERMS WITH THIS INTERNALLY.
I TOLD YOU, I WAS OUT SHOPPING
FOR MY GODDAUGHTER YESTERDAY WHO
IS 7 AND ALMOST STARTED TEARING
UP IN THE TARTH STORE.
IS IT OKAY TO SHOW THAT EMOTION
TO CHILDREN?
>> ALMOST A VICARIOUS GRIEF THAT
WE SEE THE GRIEVING OTHER PEOPLE
ARE GOING THROUGH AND WITH KIDS
SO MANY OF US FEAR LOSING THEM
THAT WHEN WE SEE OTHER PEOPLE
GRIEVING IT BRINGS OUT OUR OWN
FEARS AND WE GO THROUGH THAT
GRIEVING PROCESS WITHOUT
NECESSARILY HAVING TO.
IT IS PERFECTLY OKAY TO SHOW
EMOTION.
IT'S OKAY TO LET YOUR KIDS SEE
SOME TEARS AND SAY I REALLY FEEL
SAD ABOUT SOME THINGS THAT
HAPPENED AROUND US.
>> SO, REJECT THAT FEELING TO BE
STOIC AND BE THE STRONG, STABLE
ONE.
>> EXACTLY.
TO ME, IT TAKES MORE EMOTION TO
SHOW THE SADNESS AND THINGS THAN
IT DOES TO PUT A BRAVE FACE ON.
I KNOW WE WANT TO BE STRONG FOR
OUR KIDS, BUT SOMETIMES BEING
STRONG FOR OUR KIDS IS BEING
REAL AND HONEST AND LETTING THEM
KNOW, YOU KNOW, SOMETIMES I
DON'T ALWAYS HAVE TO BE IN
CHARGE OF MY FEELINGS AND YOU
DON'T EITHER.
MANAGE THEM, TALK ABOUT THEM
BECAUSE WHEN THEY BUILD UP, THEN
YOU CAN HAVE A DELAYED GRIEVING
PROCESS THAT COULD COME UP IN
OTHER SITUATIONS.
>> LET'S GO TO NEWTOWN.
THERE IS A COUPLE WE SPOKE WITH
THEIR TWO CHILDREN SURVIVED THE
SHOOTING.
WE WANT IT LISTEN TO WHAT THEY
SAID AND WE'LL TALK ABOUT IT ON
THE OTHER SIDE.
>> WE HAD TO PUT THE SIGN OUT IN
THE FRONT TODAY ASKING PEOPLE
NOT TO RING THE DOORBELL BECAUSE
HE STILL HASN'T INTERNALIZED THE
FACT THAT THIS GUNMAN, THIS BAD
GUY IS GONE.
AND HE WANTS TO KNOW IF THERE
ARE MORE BAD GUYS IN THE WORLD
AND I DON'T KNOW HOW TO ANSWER
THAT QUESTION.
SO, WHEN SOMEONE RINGS THE
DOORBELL, HE THINKS IT'S HIM
COMING BACK, COMING FOR HIM.
AND, SO, HE, YOU KNOW, HE -- SO,
I THINK OUR BIGGEST CONCERN NOW
IS MAKING SURE THAT WE HANDLE
HIS SENSITIVE NATURE PROPERLY
AND CAREFULLY.
>> HE WANTS TO KNOW IF THERE ARE
MORE BAD GUYS IN THE WORLD AND
IF THIS SPECIFIC BAD GUY IS
COMING BACK FOR HIM.
HOW DO THEY ANSWER IT?
>> YOU LET THEM KNOW AS PARENTS
IT'S OUR JOB AND PLACE TO
PROTECT YOU.
IN THE SCHOOL IT'S THEIR JOB TO
WE CAN'T MAKE PROMISES TO KIDS
THAT NOTHING WILL HAPPEN.
BECAUSE A PROMISE COULDN'T
ALWAYS BE KEPT.
WE HAVE TO LET THEM KNOW IN LIFE
EVENTS MAY HAPPEN, HOWEVER, IT'S
HOW WE MOVE THROUGH THEM AND AS
A FAMILY, WE LOVE AND SUPPORT
YOU, WE TAKE CARE OF YOU, WE'RE
HERE TO MAKE SURE YOU GET THE
HELP AND SUPPORT THAT YOU NEED
AND, YOU KNOW, HE HAS A WHOLE
PROCESS TO MOVE THROUGH, AS WELL
AS A GRIEVING PROCESS.
ALSO SURVIVOR'S GUILT PROCESS
THAT HE MAY GO THROUGH AS WELL
AS THE FEAR THAT SOMEONE MAY
COME OUT OF NO WHERE AND CAUSE
HARM.
THIS WILL BE A LONG PROCESS FOR
HIM TO WORK THROUGH.
>> ONE OF THE COMMON QUESTIONS
PARENTS WILL HAVE TO ANSWER,
WILL THIS HAPPEN AT MY SCHOOL?
IS THIS GOING TO HAPPEN WHERE I
PLAY?
WHAT DO YOU TELL THEM?
BECAUSE YOU CAN'T PROMISE.
>> RIGHT.
>> WHAT DO YOU SAY?
>> YOU LET THEM KNOW THAT,
AGAIN, THESE ARE THE THINGS THAT
ARE IN PLACE TO HELP KEEP YOU
SAFE.
YOU HAVE A PLAN.
SET UP A PLAN OF WHERE DO I GO
IF THIS HAPPENS.
WHO DO I CALL IF SOMETHING
HAPPENS?
THE MORE THAT THERE'S
PREPARATIONS AND THE MORE PEOPLE
HAVE A PLAN THE LESS FEAR IS
LIKELY TO STEP IN.
KIDS ARE GOING TO BE IN THAT
PLACE, IF THEY KNOW ABOUT THIS
EVENT.
MY DAUGHTER HAS NO IDEA WHAT IS
GOING ON, WE KEPT THE TVs OFF
AROUND HER PURPOSELY.
MAKING SURE SHE KNOWS WHERE TO
GO IF SOMETHING HAPPENS OR WHO
TO CALL IS IMPORTANT.
>> THERE'S ONE THING, I KNOW
WE'RE RUNNING LOW ON TIME, BUT
THERE WAS ONE TIME WHEN ADAM
LANZA WAS AS INNOCENT AS THE
CHILDREN HE KILLED.
THE CHILDREN WILL WANT TO KNOW,
WHY DID HE DO THIS?
THERE MAY NOT BE ENOUGH TIME
THAT WE GET THE ANSWERS FROM THE
INVESTIGATION, WHAT DO YOU TELL
YOUR CHILDREN NOW ABOUT WHY HE
WOULD DO THIS?
>> THAT SOMETIMES WE DON'T
ALWAYS KNOW WHY THEY DO THE
THINGS THEY DO, HOWEVER, IF WE
CAN PULL TOGETHER AS THE
COMMUNITY AND MAKE SURE KIDS
AREN'T LEFT BEHIND AND MAKE SURE
KIDS WITH NEEDS OR WITH FAMILY
STRUGGLES OR THINGS HAVE THE
CONNECTIONS THEY NEED IN THEIR
COMMUNITY TO MAKE SURE THEY HAVE
SUPPORT SYSTEMS AND THEY KNOW
HOW TO COMMUNICATE AND THAT THEY
HAVE PEOPLE WHO ARE HELPING THEM
TO MAKE THROUGH EVEN WHAT SEEMS
LIKE A SIMPLE PROBLEM, THAT MAY
BE MORE DIFFICULT INSIDE AND
THAT'S WHAT WE SEE IN THESE
SITUATIONS.
KIDS STORE THINGS INSIDE THAT
BUILD UP TO THESE ISSUES.
>> LICENSED PSYCHOLOGIST ERIC
FISHER, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> THANKS FOR HAVING ME.
>> WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN IT COMES TO
THE FINANCIAL OBSTACLES
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAND.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
♪ MOTHER AND CHILD
HOLY INFANT ♪
>> THIS WAS FROM "SATURDAY NIGHT
LIVE" LAST NIGHT.
ONE OF THE TRULY MOST POIGNANT
TRIBUTES I'VE EVER SEEN.
NOTHING BUT KIDS SINGING "SILENT
NIGHT."
NO COMEDY MONOLOGUE OPEN.
IT WAS THIS IN TRIBUTE TO THE
VICTIMS OF THE HORRIBLE SHOOTING
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
BRAVO, "SATURDAY NIGHT LIVE."
>> IT WAS VERY MOVING TO SEE.
STILL MOVING TO SEE IT AGAIN
THIS MORNING.
>>> SHOULD TELL YOU PRESIDENT
OBAMA, HE PLANS TO TRAVEL TO
CONNECTICUT TODAY.
HE WILL MEET WITH SOME OF THE
FAMILIES AND, AS WELL AS, HE
WILL MEET WITH SOME OF THE
FAMILIES AND ATTEND A VIGIL HERE
IN NEWTOWN AND ALSO TO BE
THANKING FIRST RESPONDERS HERE
IN NEWTOWN.
HE'LL BE SPEAKING AT THAT VIGIL.
AND, OBVIOUSLY, SOMETHING THAT I
THINK MANY OF THE VICTIMS AND
THE FAMILIES AND MANY OF THE
PEOPLE GRIEVING HERE ARE
LOOKING, ARE LOOKING FOR AT THIS
MOMENT.
>> THE DEADLY SHOOTING THAT
SHATTERED THIS QUIET NEW ENGLAND
TOWN IS ALSO REIGNITED ONGOING
DEBATE ABOUT THE GUN LAWS IN
AMERICA.
EVERYONE IS JUST TALKING ABOUT
THAT RIGHT NOW.
OUR WHITE HOUSE CORRESPONDENT
BRIANA KEE
BRIANNA KEILAR HAS MORE.
>> Reporter: A PROMISE FROM
PRESIDENT OBAMA TO TACKLE GUN
VIOLENCE.
>> WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO COME
TOGETHER AND TAKE MEANINGFUL
ACTION TO PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS, REGARDLESS OF THE
POLITICS.
>> Reporter: WHAT EXACTLY DOES
HE MEAN BY MEANINGFUL ACTION?
CRITICS OF THE PRESIDENT'S
RECORD ON THE ISSUE ARE PRESSING
FOR SPECIFIC PROPOSALS.
NEW YORK MAYOR MICHAEL BLOOMBERG
SAID CALLING FOR MEANINGFUL
ACTION IS NOT ENOUGH.
WE NEED IMMEDIATE ACT ACTION.
WE HEARD ALL THE RHETORIC
BEFORE.
WHAT WE HAVE NOT SEEN IS
LEADERSHIP.
NOT FROM THE WHITE HOUSE AND NOT
FROM CONGRESS.
GUN VIOLENCE HAS NOT BEEN A
PRIORITY FOR THE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION.
AS HE RAN FOR PRESIDENT IN 2008,
HE SUPPORTED RUNNING A BAN ON
ASSAULT WEAPONS.
>> KEEPING AK 47s OUT OF THE
HANDS OF CRIMINALS.
>> Reporter: ONCE SELECTED, HE
DID NOT MAKE GOOD ON HIS
CAMPAIGN PLEDGE.
THE BRADY CAMPAIGN TO PREVENT
GUN VIOLENCE GAVE THE PRESIDENT
ACROSS THE BOARD Fs ON ITS
REPORT CARD.
>> THE SENATE WILL COME TO
ORDER.
>> Reporter: A MAJOR OBSTACLE
FOR THE PRESIDENT, CONGRESS,
WHERE EVEN IN THE DEMOCRATIC
CONTROLLED SENATE, LITTLE
APPETITE TO TOUCH THE
CONTROVERSIAL ISSUE.
MULTIPLE GUN CONTROL BILLS HAVE
BEEN INTRODUCED, NOT A SINGLE
ONE HAS MADE IT TO THE FLOOR FOR
A VOTE.
THOSE INVOLVED IN THE DEBATE
OVER GUNS SAY THE PRESIDENT HAS
NUMBER OF OPTIONS, REINSTATING
SOME FORM OF THE ASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN THAT EXPIRED IN 1994,
BANNING HIGH-COUNT MAGAZINES OR
IMPROVING THE REPORTING OF
PEOPLE WITH MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES
TO MAKE SURE THEY ARE
DISQUALIFIED FROM PURCHASING
FIREARMS.
POLLS SHOW AMERICANS HAVE BECOME
ACCUSTOMED TO DAILY REPORTS OF
GUN DEATHS.
FRIDAY MORNING, A SHOOTER KILLED
A MEMPHIS POLICE OFFICER WHO WAS
A MOTHER OF FOUR.
FRIDAY NIGHT, A MAN SHOT AND
KILLED A WOMAN WORKING AT A LAS
VEGAS HOTEL BEFORE KILLING
HIMSELF.
EARLY SATURDAY MORNING IN
BIRMINGHAM, ALABAMA, POLICE
KILLED A GUNMAN INSIDE A
HOSPITAL WHERE THREE PEOPLE WERE
HURT.
BUT NEW YORK CONGRESSWOMAN
CAROLYN McCARTHY WHOSE HUSBAND
DIED AND SON WAS INJURED WHEN A
SHOOTER OPENED FIRE ON A LONG
ISLAND TRAIN IN 1993 SAID THE
CONNECTICUT SHOOTING MAY BE WHAT
FORCES PRESIDENT OBAMA AND
CONGRESS TO FINALLY ADDRESS THE
PROBLEM.
>> LET'S FACE IT, WE NEED TO
HAVE THE PRESIDENT AS THE BULLY
PULPIT ON TRYING TO GET
SOMETHING DONE.
THIS TIME WHAT I SAW WAS
DIFFERENT THAT POLITICIANS THAT
USUALLY DON'T TALK ABOUT IT WERE
TALKING ABOUT IT.
SO, THERE IS A DIFFERENCE THIS
TIME AROUND.
THERE IS A DIFFERENCE MAYBE THE
PENDULUM IS TURNING AND THE
COUNTRY IS READY TO GET SERIOUS
ABOUT THIS ISSUE.
>> JAY CARNEY SAID FRIDAY IT IS
THE TIME TO EXPRESS SYMPATHY FOR
VICTIMS' FAMILIES, NOT THE TIME
TO ENGAGE IN A POLICY DEBATE.
BUT I SPOKE WITH CONGRESSWOMAN
McCARTHY AND SHE SAID SHE CALLED
UP THE WHITE HOUSE AND SAID,
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
THIS IS SOMETHING WE SHOULD HAVE
BEEN DISCUSSING FOR YEARS.
BRIANNA KEILAR, CNN, THE WHITE
HOUSE.
[ HEART BEATING,
MONITOR BEEPING ]
Woman: WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
HOMEOWNERS INSURANCE
DOESN'T COVER FLOODS?
[ HEART RATE INCREASES ]
Man: A FEW INCHES OF WATER
CAUSED ALL THIS?
[ HEART RATE INCREASES ]
Woman #2: BUT I DON'T EVEN LIVE
NEAR THE WATER.
WHAT YOU DON'T KNOW ABOUT FLOOD
INSURANCE MAY SHOCK YOU --
INCLUDING THE FACT
THAT A PREFERRED RISK POLICY
STARTS AS LOW AS $129 A YEAR.
FOR AN AGENT, CALL THE NUMBER
THAT APPEARS ON YOUR SCREEN.
That was ME...
the day I learned I had
to start insulin
for my type 2 diabetes.
ME...
thinking my only option was the
vial and syringe dad used.
And ME...
discovering once-daily
Levemir® FlexPen.
FlexPen® is prefilled.
Doesn't need
refrigeration
for up to
42 days.
No drawing from a vial.
Dial the exact dose.
Inject by pushing a button.
FlexPen® is insulin delivery...
MY way.
Levemir® (insulin detemir
[rDNA origin] injection)
is a long-acting insulin
used to control high blood sugar
in adults and children
with diabetes and is not
recommended to treat
diabetic ketoacidosis.
Do not use Levemir® if
you are allergic
to any of its ingredients.
The most common side effect
is low blood sugar,
which may cause
symptoms such as sweating,
shakiness, confusion,
and headache.
Severe low blood sugar can be
serious and life threatening.
Ask your healthcare provider
about alcohol use,
operating machinery, or driving.
Other possible side
effects include
injection site reactions.
Tell your healthcare provider
about all medicines you take
and all of your
medical conditions.
Get medical help right away
if you experience
serious allergic
reactions, such as body rash,
trouble with breathing, fast
heartbeat, or sweating.
With FlexPen®... say good night
to vial and syringe.
Ask your doctor about
Levemir® FlexPen.