MANY MORE LOOKED AT THE POST.
I APPRECIATE YOU IMPORTANT BEING
WITH ME TODAY.
I'M CAROL COSTELLO.
"NEWSROOM" CONTINUES RIGHT NOW
WITH ASHLEIGH BANFIELD.
>>> HELLO, EVERYONE.
I'M ASHLEIGH BANFIELD LIVE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
A TOWN IN MOURNING TO SAY THE
LEAST.
THE IMAGES THAT WE HAVE SEEN
THROUGHOUT THIS TOWN ARE
HEARTBREAKING.
MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS ON SEVERAL
STREET CORNERS.
EVERYTHING FROM TEDDY BEARS TO
CANDLES TO FLOWERS AND ANGELS'
WINGS.
IT IS A BEAUTIFUL COMMUNITY
HERE.
JUST SO QUIET AND PRISTINE AND
YOU CALL IT BECAUSE WHAT YOU CAN
HEAR ABOUT NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
AND IT IS SO FILLED WITH GRIEF.
IT IS ONLY THE BEGINNING,
THOUGH, AS THIS TOWN PREPARES TO
BURY THOSE WHO WERE KILLED ON
FRIDAY.
THERE WILL BE SO MANY BURIALS.
THE FIRST OF THE FUNERALS BEGINS
TODAY AT 1:00 P.M.
THESE WOULD BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN,
JACK PINTO, NOAH POZNER.
IT IS GOING TO BE A TRAGIC
SEVERAL WEEKS.
NO ONE KNEW THAT MORE THAN
PRESIDENT OBAMA WHO CAME HERE TO
SPEAK TO THIS TOWN AT A TOUCHING
MEMORIAL LAST NIGHT.
>> SURELY WE DO BETTER THAN
THIS.
IF THERE IS EVEN ONE STEP WE CAN
TAKE TO SAVE ANOTHER CHILD OR
ANOTHER PARENT OR ANOTHER TOWN
FROM THE GRIEF THAT'SES HAVE  E
VISITED TUCSON, AURORA, OAK
CREEK AND NEWTOWN, COMMUNITIES
FROM COLUMBINE TO BLACKSBURG
BEFORE THAT, SURELY WE HAVE AN
OBLIGATION TO TRY.
>> SURELY WE HAVE AN OBLIGATION
TO TRY, AS NEWTOWN REMEMBERS.
HERE ARE SOME OTHER TRAGEDIES.
ADAM LANZA HAS BEEN IDENTIFIED
OFFICIALLY AS THE KILLER.
THAT IS HIS MOTHER IN BETTER
TIMES ON THE RIGHT.
NANCY LANZA.
HER HOME REMAINS A CRIME SCENE.
IT WILL REMAIN SO FOR QUITE SOME
TIME.
THE POLICE AREN'T GIVING ANY
INDICATION RIGHT NOW AS TO A
MOTIVE.
THEY SAY THEY ARE ACCUMULATING
QUITE A BIT OF EVIDENCE,
INCLUDING THE HARD DRIVE OF HIS
COMPUTER AT HOME.
APE THERE COMPUTER, THOUGH,
SMASHED.
THEY ALSO SAY THAT TWO ADULTS AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY ARE
RECOVERING FROM GUNSHOT WOUNDS.
NOW WE ARE -- WE ARE NOW HEARING
WOULD SURVIVORS WHO WERE SHOT.
THEY ARE EXPECTED TO BE ABLE TO
HELP IN THE INVESTIGATION.
THE POLICE SAYING TODAY WHEN IT
IS APPROPRIATE, WHEN THE TIME IS
RIGHT, THEY WILL BE ABLE TO
QUESTION THOSE TWO ADULTS
FURTHER.
WE DON'T KNOW WHEN THOSE
600-SOME-ODD KIDS WILL BE ABLE
TO RETURN TO SCHOOL.
THOSE CHILDREN FROM SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
WE ARE TOLD THAT SCHOOL IS
CLOSED INDEFINITELY UNTIL THEY
ARE ABLE TO REOPEN IT.
BUT IT IS A CRIME SCENE AND
THERE IS A LOT OF PROCESSING.
THIS MORNING, WE WERE TOLD THAT
IT COULD BE MONTHS AND MONTHS
BEFORE THAT SCHOOL OPENS.
THE SAME GOES FOR THE LANZA
FAMILIAR FAMILY HOME.
HERE IS THE LATEST WORD FROM THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE THIS
MORNING.
>> WE ARE HOLDING BOTH CRIME
SCENES, THE SCHOOL AND SECONDARY
CRIME SCENE, INDEFINITELY.
WE SEIZED IT UNDER SEARCH
SXWARPTS WE WILL HOLD THOSE
LOCATIONS UNTIL WE HAVE
COMPLETED OUR WORK AND WE FEEL
IT IS APPROPRIATE TO LET THEM
GO.
IT IS NOT TO READ ANYTHING INTO
THAT, IT IS COMMON PRACTICE TO
DO THAT, TO HOLD ON TO THE CRIME
SCENE, AS LONG AS AS NEEDED FOR
INVESTIGATIVE PURPOSES.
>> MY COLLEAGUE, DON LEMON,
JOINS ME NOW.
YOU HAVE BEEN DOING A LOT OF
COVERAGE, DON, ON THIS SINCE
THIS BROKE ON FRIDAY.
I WANT TO TALK ABOUT THE
SCHOOLS.
THEY HAVE BEEN TRYING TO PIECE
TOGETHER SOME KIND OF PLAN NOT
ONLY FOR THE KIDS AT SANDY HOOK
BUT ALSO ALL OF THE KIDS IN THE
DISTRICT HERE IN NEWTOWN.
WHAT DO THEY KNOW SO FAR?
>> NOT ONLY FOR THE KIDS,
IMPORTANT THE TEACHERS AS WELL.
AND STAFF.
THEY DON'T FEEL SAFE.
THEY ARE BEEFING AND ADDING
OFFICERS.
YOU HEARD HIM TALK ABOUT IN HIS
PRESS CONFERENCE.
BEEFING UP SECURITY.
OFFICERS AT SCHOOLS.
THE SCHOOL OFFICERS ARE ALREADY
THERE.
THEY WILL MAKE SURE THAT THEY
HAVE MORE.
THAT'S WHAT THEY ARE DOING, TO
ASSURE SAFETY AS MUCH AS THEY
CAN AS POSSIBLE FOR PEOPLE WHO
ARE GOING BACK TO SCHOOL.
AND ARE CONCERNED ABOUT THIS.
THEY SAID THEY ARE MEETING WITH
TEACHERS AS WELL.
>> NO ONE TODAY.
>> NO ONE IS BACK AT SCHOOL BUT
THEY ARE MEETING WITH TEACHERS
AND HAVE PLANS TO MEET WITH THEM
ALL WEEK UNTIL THEY FIGURE OUT
EXACTLY WHEN THEY WANT TO GO
BACK.
>> IT IS LIKELY THE REST OF THE
CHILDREN OUTSIDE OF SANDY HOOK
WILL BE GOING BACK TO THEIR
SCHOOLS AROUND THIS DISTRICT
TOMORROW.
OBVIOUSLY WITH A -- WHOLE OTHER
PLAN IN MODE FOR HOW TO HANDLE
THE CRISIS THAT HAS HAPPENED.
>> IT IS A WORKING PLAN.
YOU KNOW, WHAT HAPPENED HERE WAS
EXTRAORDINARY.
AS YOU HAVE BEEN WALKING AROUND
HERE AND TALKING TO PEOPLE AND I
HAVE, EVERYONE IS WEARING THEIR
HEARTS ON THEIR SLEEVE.
THEY WALK UP AND WANT TO HUG US
AND TALK TO US EVEN THE POLICE.
>> EVEN THE POLICE.
>> NOT SOMETHING WE SEE WHEN WE
ARRIVE ON THESE EMERGENCY
LOCATION WHICH IS YOU AND I HAVE
DONE FOR SO MANY YEARS.
THERE'S OFTEN A TENSION BETWEEN
THE POLICE AND THE PRESS AND THE
PEOPLE.
I'M NOT FEELING THAT AS MUCH
HERE AS I EVER HAVE.
>> TO HAVE PEOPLE WALK UP AND
USUALLY THEY ARE LIKE OH, MY
GOSH, YOU ARE TAKING OVER OUR
TOWN.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR BEING
HERE.
IT IS VERY REFRESHING IN A WAY
AND IT ALSO LETS US KNOW THAT AS
TRAGIC AS THIS IS, AND YOU HAVE
KIDS WHO ARE IN SCHOOL IN
CONNECTICUT, THAT THIS -- THE
COMMUNITIES AROUND HERE, PEOPLE
REALLY PULL TOGETHER AND
REACHING OUT AND THEY WILL GET
BETTER.
>> THERE ARE PEOPLE THAT I JUST
ENCOUNTERED THIS MORNING FROM
20, 30, 45 MINUTES AWAY THAT
HAVE COME TO BRING TEDDY BEARS
AND JUST SEE OR JUST BE OR JUST
FEEL OR JUST AT LEAST SHOW THAT
THEY CARE.
ONE OTHER QUICK THING I WANTED
TO ASK YOU, AS FAR AS THOSE 600
OR SO KIDS FROM SANDY HOOK, THEY
ARE NOT GOING TO BE GOING BACK
FOR SEVERAL MONTHS TO THAT
SCHOOL BUT THEY ARE MAKE
ARRANGEMENTS AT THE CHALK HILL
SCHOOL IN MONROE.
>> THAT WAS THE INITIAL WORD.
WE BOUGHT THE OFFICIAL WORD LAST
NIGHT.
AGAIN, AS WE SAY, IT IS A WORK
IN PROGRESS BECAUSE THEY HAVE TO
TALK TO PARENTS AND THEY HAVE TO
TALK INFORM TO TEACHERS AND
STAFF AND MAKE SURE THAT THE
FACILITY IS BIG ENOUGH TO TAKE
IN ALL OF THE STUDENTS THAT ARE
AT THE SCHOOL HERE, THAT --
WON'T BE GOING BACK TO THE
SCHOOL HERE.
I WANT TO SAY THIS JUST BEFORE
WE GO.
I THOUGHT ONE OF THE PEOPLE I
SPOKE TO YESTERDAY WHO KNEW
NANCY LANZA, ONE OF HER FRIENDS,
SAID OUR TOWN HAS CHANGED
FOREVER.
AND IT IS DEFINITELY CHANGED
OVER THE LAST COUPLE OF DAYS.
HE SAYS AS WE WERE TALKING,
SIRENS WERE GOING OFF.
THERE WAS A MOTORCADE GOING BY
OF SOME DIGNITARY.
IT WASN'T THE.
.
HE SAID IT IS LIKE WE ARE IN THE
MIDDLE OF A CIRCUS.
EXCEPT NOBODY IS HAVING FUN WITH
THIS.
THAT SUMS UP WHAT IS HAPPENING.
>> I THOUGHT THAT FRIDAY MIGHT
AS I WAS DRIVATION WAY FROM THIS
TOWN LATE.
I THINK IT WAS MID MIGHT WHEN WE
MIGHT HAVE WRAPPED UP HERE.
I WAS DRIVING ALONG AND SEEING
CHRISTMAS LIGHTS AND SEEING ALL
THE LIGHTS ON INSIDE OF THESE
HOMES.
REALIZING A LOT OF THESE HOMES
MAY BE THE ONES PEAKED.
AND THERE WERE SO MANY THAT I
THOUGHT THIS TOWN WILL NEVER,
EVER BE THE SAME.
WITHOUT QUESTION.
>> THOSE 20 KIDS WILL NOT BE
RUNNING DOWN THE STAIRS AND
BOLTING TOWARDS A CHRISTMAS TREE
TO SEE WHAT SANTA LEFT THEM.
INSTEAD THEIR PARENTS ARE TRYING
TO PICK OUT COFFINS FOR THEM.
THAT'S A SAD REALITY.
>> DON, THANK YOU.
STAND BY, IF YOU WILL.
ALISON KOSIK HAS BEEN WORKING ON
THE OTHER SIDE OF THIS STORY
WHICH IS THE INVESTIGATION WHICH
HAS TO GO ON AS THOSE WHO
MORNING AND PLAN THEIR BURIALS.
THOSE POLICE OFFICERS WHO ARE
NOW BEING DISPATCHED TO COVER
THE FUNERALS AND DO SECURITY FOR
FUNERALS ARE ALSO WORKING ON THE
INVESTIGATION OF ADAM LANZA, WHY
HE DID WHAT HE DID, HOW HE DID
WHAT HE DID.
AND EXACTLY HOW IT ALL
TRANSPIRED.
STILL A TIMELINE ISN'T VERY
CLEAR.
ALISON KOSIK IS LIVE OUT IN
FRONT OF THE LANZA HOME.
WHAT ARE YOU FINDING OUT TODAY?
>> FIRST OF ALL, WE ARE STANDING
IN FRONT OF THE LANZA HOME.
IT IS THE ONE BEHIND ME HERE ON
THE HILL.
IT IS PICTURESQUE WHEN YOU LOOK
AT IT.
IT IS HUGE.
SITTING ON A BEAUTIFUL GREEN
LAWN.
THERE IS A WREATH OVER THE FRONT
DOOR.
THIS, THOUGH IS STILL AN ACTIVE
CRIME SCENE AND THE
INVESTIGATION REALLY DOES
CONTINUE INTO WHAT ADAM LANZA
WAS DOING IN THE DAYS AND IN THE
WEEKS AND MONTHS BEFORE THIS
MASSACRE ON FRIDAY.
INVESTIGATORS NOW HAVE PROOF
THAT THE GUNMAN -- WAS -- AT
LEAST ONE SHOOTING RANGE.
THEY ARE NOT SAY WHEN, THEY ARE
NOT SAYING WHERE.
THEY ARE ALSO SAYING THAT HIS
MOTHER, NANCY LANZA, WHO ALSO
LIVED WITH HIM AT THE HOUSE
BEHIND ME, WHO HE SHOT AND
KILLED BEFORE HE WENT TO THE
SCHOOL, THAT SHE ALSO VISITED AT
LEAST ONE SHOOTING RANGE SEVERAL
TIMES.
THEY ARE NOT SAYING WHEN.
THEY ARE NOT SAYING WHERE.
THERE WAS A PRESS CONFERENCE A
SHORT TIME AGO WHERE POLICE WERE
ASKED IF THEY RECOVERED ANYTHING
FROM A SMASHED HARD DRIVE AND
THE WAY -- THE LIEUTENANT PUT IT
IS THAT THEY ARE INVESTIGATING
ALL ELECTRONIC EVIDENCE IN THIS
CASE.
>> I'M JUST CURIOUS, OFTENTIMES
WHEN WE COVER THESE TRAGEDIES,
THE PERSON AT THE CENTER IS --
LEAVES SOME KIND AFTER FOOTPRINT
BEHIND, FACEBOOK PAGE, TWITTER
ACCOUNT, PHOTOGRAPHS FROM THE
YEARBOOK.
THERE SEEMS TO BE SOME KIND OF
A -- AT LEAST A PHOTOGRAPHIC
PERSONALITY WE CAN PUT TOGETHER.
WE CAN GET INTERVIEWS WITH
PEOPLE WHO KNEW THEM TO AT LEAST
TRY TO PIECE TOGETHER WHAT KIND
OF PEOPLE THEY WERE.
THIS IS ONE OF THOSE STORIES
WHERE WE HAVE HAD A TERRIBLY
DIFFICULT TIME FIGURING OUT WHO
THIS YOUNG MAN WAS.
OR EVEN FIND OUT WHAT HE LOOKS
LIKE.
WHY IS THAT?
>> IT HAS BEEN VERY TOUGH
BECAUSE THIS IS A FAMILY THAT --
MOTHER AND SON WHO LIVED BEHIND
ME, THEY KEPT TO THEMSELVES.
THEY REALLY WEREN'T THAT
SOCIAB
SOCIABLE.
THAT'S WHAT WE HEAR FROM
NEIGHBORS.
WE KNOW WHAT HE DID ON FRIDAY,
CAME OUT INTO THE OPEN.
HE SHOT HIS WAY IN A THAT
SCHOOL.
HE FIRED DOZENS OF BULLETS INTO
HIS VICTIMS, USING A
SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPON.
DID YOU KNOW HE HAD HUNDREDS OF
UNUSED BULLETS ON HIM.
HE WAS REALLY OUT TO KILL.
AND -- AT THE SAME NEWS
CONFERENCE I'M TALKING ABOUT,
SOMEONE HAD ASKED THE
LIEUTENANT, WAS HE OUT TO KILL
THAT MUCH?
THE POLICE DIDN'T WANT TO GO
THAT FAR.
LISTEN HOW POLICE PUT IT.
>> I CAN'T SPECULATE WHAT WOULD
HAVE OCCURRED.
THAT WOULD BE WRONG ON MY PART.
I CAN TELL YOU THAT THE --
FACULTY AND STAFF IN THAT SCHOOL
DID EVERYTHING THAT THEY
POSSIBLY COULD TO PROTECT THOSE
CHILDREN.
I CAN TELL YOU THAT THE FIRST
RESPONDERS THAT GOT THERE AT THE
SCENE AND ENTERED THE SCHOOL AND
SAVED MANY HUMAN LIVES.
I CAN TELL YOU IT BROKE OUR
HEARTS WE COULDN'T SAVE THEM
ALL.
>> AUTHORITIES FOUND THREE
WEAPONS IN THE CLASSROOM INSIDE
OF THAT SCHOOL.
AND THEY FOUND ONE OTHER WEAPON,
FOURTH WEAPON, SHOTGUN INSIDE OF
HIS CAR THAT WAS PARKED IN THE
SCHOOL PARKING LOT.
>> ALL RIGHT, ALISON KOSIK FOR
US LIVE THIS MORNING.
THANK YOU FOR THAT.
>>> OBVIOUSLY THE POLICE HAVE
SAID THAT THEY HAVE AN
EXTRAORDINARY AMOUNT OF WORK
AHEAD OF THEM.
NOT ONLY ARE THEY PROCESSING
THAT SCHOOL AS A CRIME SCENE,
WHICH THE OFFICER SAID THIS
MORNING COULD TAKE MONTHS, BUT
THEY ARE ALSO TRYING TO FIND OUT
WHY THIS YOUNG MAN DID WHAT HE
DID.
HOW HE PERPETRATED THIS CRIME
AND IF THERE WAS ANYTHING ANYONE
COULD HAVE DONE TO PREVENT IT.
WE HAVE MORE FROM DR. SANJAY
GUPTA AFTER THE BREAK.
I GAVE BIRTH TO MY DAUGHTER
ON MAY 18TH,
FIVE DAYS LATER,
I HAD A MASSIVE HEART ATTACK.
BAYER ASPIRIN WAS THE FIRST
THING THE EMTS GAVE ME.
NOW, I'M ON
A BAYER ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Male Announcer ] BE SURE
TO TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE YOU BEGIN
AN ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Woman ]
LEARN FROM MY STORY.
♪
>>> WE WILL MOVE ON.
WE WILL NEVER FORGET.
WE WILL, IN MANY WAYS, BECOME
STRONGER FROM WHAT HAS
TRANSPIRED.
AND WE WILL GET BETTER.
>> THE CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR
SPEAKING AT A MEMORIAL.
TOUCHING MEMORIAL LAST NIGHT.
HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE CROWDING INTO
THE HIGH SCHOOL HERE WHERE THE
PRESIDENT WAS AS WELL.
SAYING THAT WE WILL GET BETTER.
MUST HAVE TOWN WILL GET BETTER
BUT THEY WILL BE FOREVER
SCARRED.
THE EMOTIONAL TOLL THAT THIS
WILL TAKE NOT ONLY ON THE PEOPLE
HERE BUT PEOPLE EVERYWHERE.
JUST A PERSONAL ANECDOTE, I
DON'T LIVE FAR FROM HERE.
I HAVE TWO SMALL CHILDREN IN AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE HAVE BEEN GETTING REGULAR
UPDATES AND E-MAILS HOW OUR
SCHOOL WILL BE HANDLING THIS AND
OUR DISTRICT WILL BE HANDLE
THING.
THIS JUST YOU AN IDEA OF
REVERBERATION THIS KIND OF A
TRAGEDY IS HAVING CLOSE BY.
THE SECURITY THAT WILL BE BEEFED
UP AT OTHER SCHOOLS AROUND THIS
COMMUNITY.
THE MENTAL HEALTH PROFESSIONALS
THAT ARE GOING TO BE ON SITE.
THE MEETINGS THAT ARE TAKING
PLACE.
THIS IS IN MY SCHOOL DISTRICT.
JUST A FEW TOWNS AWAY.
JUST TO HANDLE WHAT THESE KIDS
WILL LIKELY BE COMING TO SCHOOL
WITH BECAUSE THEY WILL HAVE
HEARD IT ON THE NEWS OR THEY
WILL HAVE HEARD IT FROM THEIR
PARENTS.
OR THEY WILL HAVE HEARD IT ON
THE PLAYGROUND.
DR. SANJAY GUPTA JOINS ME TO
TALK ABOUT NOT ONLY WHAT
OBVIOUSLY THESE CHILDREN IN
NEWTOWN ARE GOING THROUGH BUT
ALL KIDS AS WE GO THROUGHOUT
CONNECTICUT, GEORGIA,
CALIFORNIA, WASHINGTON STATE.
I MEAN, IT IS REALLY A POWERFUL,
POWERFUL THING TO PROCESS.
>> AND WE KNOW THAT EVEN,
OBVIOUSLY, PEOPLE WHO ARE MOST
DIRECTLY INVOLVED ARE GOING TO
HAVING THE HIGHEST IMPACT AND
GREATEST IMPACT ON THEM.
BUT, YEAH, YOU ARE RIGHT.
THE PEOPLE MORE REMOTE THAT HAVE
BEEN WATCHING IT, LEARNING ABOUT
IT, TALKING ABOUT IT, THERE HAVE
BEEN STUDIES ON THIS AND FIND
THAT THERE IS A COMPONENT OF
POST-TRAUMATIC STRESS EVEN IN
THOSE POPULATIONS.
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT CHILDREN
HERE.
WE TYPICALLY THINK ABOUT
POST-TRAUMATIC STRESS IN ADULTS.
BUT EVEN AFTER VIRGINIA TECH,
FOR EXAMPLE, AFTER A FEW MONTHS
LATER, 15% OF PEOPLE WHO WERE
INVOLVED -- WENT TO COLLEGES,
WHO -- WATCHED THIS VERY
CLOSELY, STILL HAD SOME
COMPONENT OF IT.
77% OF STUDENTS AT VIRGINIA TECH
HAD IT.
OBVIOUSLY MUCH HIGHER IN THE
PEOPLE MOST --
>> 77%?
>> THREE TO FOUR MONTHS LATER.
IT IS SIGNIFICANT.
THERE'S A COUPLE OF THINGS TO
KEEP IN MIND.
ONE IS THAT THE QUICKER SOME OF
THOSE SYMPTOMS AND SIGNS ARE
RECOGNIZED AND DEALT WITH, THE
MUCH BETTER PROGNOSIS PEOPLE
HAVE.
THESE ARE TOUGH CONVERSATIONS
BUT, YOU KNOW, THEY ARE
IMPORTANT IN TERMS OF TRYING TO
WARD OFF THE SYMPTOM.
>> MY SCHOOL DISTRICT SUGGESTED
WE TALK TO OUR CHILDREN AND LET
THEM KNOW.
HI THAT CONVERSATION WITH MY
KIDS ON SATURDAY.
I WASN'T QUITE SURE WHAT TO MAKE
OF THEIR REACTION.
THEY SEEMED VERY DISINTERESTED.
THEY WERE PLAYING WITH THEIR
TOYS WHILE I WAS TELLING THEM.
I TRIED TO MITIGATE SOME OF THE
DETAIL OBVIOUSLY AND THE --
DEVASTATE FACT.
BUT I WONDER IF THIS IS
SOMETHING WHERE, YOU KNOW, IN A
COUPLE OF WEEKS OR MONTHS, THEY
ARE GOING TO START QUESTIONING
ME MORE.
WHERE IT WILL START TO SETTLE IN
AND AFFECT THEM AT A DIFFERENT
TIME.
>> NO QUESTION.
YOU HAVE JUST -- GAVE THEM A
TEXTBOOK EXAMPLE OF THAT.
FIRST OF ALL, HOW CHILDREN --
YOU KNOW, SORT OF REACT.
YOU KNOW, THEY CAN BE -- THEY
CAN BE DECIDEDLY NONVERBAL.
YOU WATCH HOW THEY ARE PLAYING,
HOW THEY ARE INTERACTING WITH
EACH OTHER.
MOST IMPORTANTLY, HOW THEY ARE
SLEEPING.
THAT'S A VERY, VERY POWERFUL
PREDICTOR OF HOW THEY ARE GOING
TO COPE IN THE LONG RUN.
THEY MAY SEEM DISINTERESTED.
THERE ARE STAGES TO GRIEF.
YOU TALKED ABOUT THIS.
PEOPLE KNOW THAT AND CHILDREN
CAN GO THROUGH THE STAGES
DIFFERENTLY THAN ADULTS.
YOU ARE RIGHT.
THAT CONVERSATION COULD HAPPEN
AT ANY TIME.
>> QUICKLY LET ME ASK YOU THIS.
SOME OF THOSE CHILDREN WHEN
WITNESSED THIS, THEY WERE ASKED
TO AVERT THEIR EYES AS THEY LEFT
THE BUILDING.
CLEARLY, THEY ARE GOING TO NEED
SO MUCH CARE AND ATTENTION.
CAN WE HELP THEM?
CAN WE TRULY HELP THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN GET OVER WHAT THEY HAVE
GONE THROUGH?
>> I THINK SO.
IF THERE IS ANY GOOD NEWS IN
THIS, THAT SEEMS TO BE A
CONSISTENT ANSWER I RECEIVED AS
WELL FROM THE EXPERTS WHO DEAL
WITH THIS SORT OF THING.
AGAIN, EVERYTHING HERE IS
UNPRECEDENTED.
YOU CAN'T SAY -- NO TEMPLATE.
YOU KNOW, THEY -- THEY CAN --
GET OVER IT IN THE SENSE THAT,
YOU KNOW, GO ON TO HAVE
FUNCTIONAL LIVES.
GETTING OVER IT DOESN'T MEAN
FORGETTING IT OR IGNORING IT.
GOING ON TO HAVE NORMAL LIVES
AND NORMAL ACTIVITIES AND DALE
LIVING, I THINK ABSOLUTELY.
>> DR. GUPTA, I WISH WE COULD
TALK UNDER DIFFERENT
CIRCUMSTANCES.
I ALWAYS APPRECIATE YOUR
INSIGHT.
>> YOURS AS WELL.
I WATCH PROSECUTED THE
BEGINNING.
BEING A PARENT MYSELF, YOU
REALLY -- I THINK YOU BROUGHT IT
HOME AND MADE IT SOMETHING, YOU
KNOW --
>> FINDING ALL OF OUR COLLEAGUES
ARE AFFECTED IN A WAY I HAVE
NEVER SEEN BEFORE.
REMINDS ME OF 9/11.
STAY ON THE SCENE WITH US AND WE
WILL CONTINUE TO BRING YOU THE
DETAILS AS WE CAN.
A VERY DIFFICULT STORY FOR
EVERYONE.
IT IS IMPORTANT WE SHARE THIS
BECAUSE A LOT OF PEOPLE ACROSS
THE COUNTRY AND AROUND THE WORLD
ARE FEELING IT.
FEELING IT LIKE WE ARE AND THEY
ARE FEELING AND IT WANT TO POUR
OUT THEIR HEARTS TO THIS
COMMUNITY AS WELL.
♪
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS I WILL
USE WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE
HOLDS TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW
CITIZENS FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT TO
MENTAL HEALTH PROFESSIONALS,
PARENTS, EDUCATORS IN AN EFFORT
AIMED AT PREVENTING MORE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS.
>> SOME OF THE MOVING MOMENTS
FROM THE MEMORIAL LAST NIGHT
HERE IN THE TOWN OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AT THE HIGH SCHOOL.
IF YOU DIDN'T SEE IT, IT WAS
JUST SUCH AN EMOTIONAL TIME
BETWEEN THE INTERFAITH MEMBERS
OF THE COMMUNITY HERE AND THE
PRESIDENT HIMSELF.
THERE HAVE BEEN A COUPLE OF
DIFFERENT REACTIONS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY TO WHAT HAS BEEN
HAPPENING.
I MEAN THIS IN A TECHNICAL WAY.
SAN FRANCISCO-OAKLAND AREA,
THERE WAS A -- GUN BUY BACK.
SEVERAL DIFFERENT EVENTS.
GUN BUY BACK EVENTS.
THEY WERE PLANNED BEFORE WHAT
HAPPENED HERE IN NEWTOWN.
BUT THERE WERE MUCH LARGER
CROWDS TURNING OUT THAN THEY HAD
EXPECTED.
YOU CAN SEE SOME OF THE EVIDENCE
OF WHAT HAD BEEN BROUGHT IN.
PEOPLE WERE GIVEN $200 TO BRING
IN THEIR ZBNS JUST HAND THEM
OVER TO THE AUTHORITIES.
ING THE LOCAL REPORTS SAY ABOUT
600 GUNS WERE TURNED IN OVER THE
COURSE OF THINGS EVENT.
SOME PEOPLE SAYING TO THE
AUTHORITIES THAT THEY JUST
NEEDED TO HAVE THOSE GUNS OUT OF
THEIR HOMES.
THE PRESIDENT IS CALLING FOR,
QUOTE, MEANINGFUL ACTION ON
GUNS.
MANY DEMOCRATS ARE CALLING FOR
STRICT NEW GUN CONTROL LAWS.
OF COURSE THE ASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN EXPIRED IN 2004.
THERE IS SOME TALK THAT MAYBE,
MAYBE BRINGING THAT BACK WOULD
BE A FOOT.
THE EFFECT OF WHAT YOU SAW IN IS
AN PLAN AND OAKLAND WAS
DIFFERENT ELSEWHERE.
FOR INSTANCE, LIKE ARIZONA.
SOME OF THE GUN BUYERS IN
ARIZONA BECAME VERY AFRAID
ACTUALLY THAT THIS NEW NATIONAL
CONVERSATION, PARTICULARLY MY --
WHAT HAPPENED THIS BEAUTIFUL
TOWN, COULD MAKE IT VERY
DIFFICULT ALL OF A SUDDEN TO GET
CERTAIN KINDS OF GUNS.
EGG I
EGGING.
>> Reporter: COLUMBINE, VIRGINIA
TECH, TUCSON, MOVIE THEATER IN
COLORADO, SIKH TEMPLE IN
WISCONSIN, OREGON SHOPPING MALL.
EVEN WITH THOSE MASS SHOOTINGS,
IT HAS BECOME EASIER FOR MOST
AMERICANS TO CARRY A GUN, OWN AN
ASSAULT RIFLE, OR USE HIGH
CAPACITY MAGAZINES.
IN THE AFTERMATH OF CONNECTICUT,
VOICES, MOST NOTABLY FROM
TEARFUL PRESIDENT OBAMA, ARE
CALLING FOR TIGHTER GUN CONTROL.
YOU WON'T HEAR THEM IN A
CALIFORNIA GUN SHOW HELD THE DAY
AFTER THE CONNECTICUT MASSACRE.
>> EVERYBODY IS IN A PANIC.
I HAVE NEVER SEEN SO MANY PEOPLE
AT A GUN SHOW.
WORRIED ABOUT THE SECOND
AMENDMENT RIGHTS.
>> Reporter: THERE IS SYMPATHY
FOR THE VICTIM.
>> IT IS HORRIBLE THAT THOSE
CHILDREN DID DIE.
>> Reporter: BUT THE SOLUTION
HERE, MORE GUNS.
>> IF ONE OF THOSE TEACHERS, ONE
OF THEM, FACULTY MEMBER A
JANITOR, HAD A GUN, BAM, HE
WOULD HAVE KILLED -- NOTHING
COMPARED TO WHAT HE WAS CAPABLE
OF DOING.
YOU HAVE TO ALLOW US TO PROTECT
OURSELF.
>> THE GUNS DIDN'T KILL PEOPLE.
IT WAS THE PERSON WHO WAS CRAZY.
HE WAS MENTALLY UNSTABLE.
>> Reporter: THE COLORADO
GOVERNOR SAID TWO DAYS BEFORE
THE CONNECTICUTSHOOTING.
>> I TOOK MY 10-YEAR-OLD SON OUT
SHOOTING PIGEONS TWO WEEKS AGO.
THAT PART OF IT -- THAT PART OF
A GUN CULTURE IS SO DEEPLY
INGRAINED IN COLORADO, IN THE
UNITED STATES.
LITERALLY ALMOST EVERYWHERE,
THAT TO TRY TO CHANGE IT WOULD
BE, YOU KNOW, A VERY STEEP HILL
TO CLIMB.
>> Reporter: THERE IS A
PRECEDENT.
GREAT BRITAIN BANNED NEARLY ALL
HAPPENED GUNS AFTER A MASS
SHOOTING AT A PRIMARY SCHOOL IN
1986.
PARENTS REFLECTED A NATION
DIVIDED OVER GUN CONTROL.
>> SHOULD BE MORE GUN CONTROL,
YES.
>> Reporter: WHY DO YOU THINK
THAT N.
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, GUNS ARE --
GUNS ARE -- IN THE WRONG HANDS,
ARE VERY DANGEROUS.
>> GUNS DON'T KILL PEOPLE.
PEOPLE KILL PEOPLE.
>> DEFINITELY SHOULD BE A GUN
CONTROL.
SHOULD BE MONTH GUNS OUT WILL.
LOT OF CRAZY PEOPLE DON'T KNOW
HOW TO HANDLE GUNS.
>> I DON'T THINK TAKING GUNS OUT
OF CIVILIANS WHO ARE GOOD
CONTRIBUTING MEMBERS OF SOCIETY
ARE THE ANSWER.
>> Reporter: SINCE THE
CONNECTICUT SHOOTING MORE THAN
100,000 AMERICANS HAVE SIGNED AN
ONLINE PETITION DEMANDING
PRESIDENT OBAMA PRODUCE
LEGISLATION LIMITING ACCESS TO
GUNS.
>> CASEY JOINS ME LIVE NOW
OUTSIDE OF AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IN PHOENIX.
WATCHING THAT STORY, YOU -- YOU
ARE REMINDED OF THE
JUXTAPOSITION OF THE OPINION
THAT -- SO MANY PEOPLE WANT
THEIR FREEDOMS AND THEIR RIGHT
TO BEAR ARMS AND -- SO MANY
PEOPLE FEAR WHAT THAT FREEDOM
COULD BRING AS WELL.
TALK TO ME ABOUT WHAT YOU ARE
FEELING IN THAT COMMUNITY TODAY.
>> Reporter: WELL, IT IS REALLY
A COMMUNITY DIVIDED.
IT IS A NATION DIVIDED ON THIS
ISSUE.
THAT LAST PARENT WHO WAS IN OUR
REPORT WHO WE LOCAL
CHURCH HERE AND HE SAYS HE
OR MORE
PEOPLE TO BE ARMED.
YOU HEAR THAT A LOT FROM GUN
RIGHTS ADVOCATES.
AT THAT GUN SHOW IN CALIFORNIA
OVER THE WEEKEND, PEOPLE WERE
BUSILY BUYING GUNS.
AFRAID THAT GUN CONTROL
LEGISLATION COULD BE ON THE
HORIZON.
WANTING TO GET THE GUNS THEY
WANTED BEFORE THAT HAPPENED.
ALSO TALKED TO A LOT OF PARENTS
IN PLACES LIKE THAT ARE VERY
AFRAID AND SAY NOW IS THE TIME
IMPORTANT GUN CONTROL.
IT IS LONG OVERDUE.
THEY A PLACE THIS
WHERE THEY ARE SUPPOSED TO BE
SAFE AND REALIZING THEY ARE NOT.
>> THANK YOU FOR THAT.
I JUST WANTED TO QUOTE A
STATISTIC FOR YOU.
IN CASE YOU ARE WONDER BEING THE
NUMBER OF PEOPLE WHO ARE
INTERESTED IN BUYING GUNS, THE
FBI IS REPORTING THAT JUST THIS
YEAR, JUST THIS YEAR, 2012, 16.8
MILLION BACKGROUND CHECKS WERE
PERFORMED FOR GUN PURCHASES.
AND HOW DOES THAT COMPARE TO,
SAY, TEN YEARS AGO?
THAT IS DOUBLE THE NUMBER THAN A
DECADE AGO.
BACK AFTER THIS.
♪
(Announcer) When Subaru owners
look in the mirror,
they see more than themselves.
So we celebrate our year-end
with the "share the love" event.
Get a great deal on a new Subaru
and 250 dollars goes to your
choice of five charities.
By the end of this, our fifth
year,
our total can reach almost 25
million dollars.
It's a nice reflection on us
all.
Now through January 2nd.
YOU'LL ALSO CARE ABOUT
OUR NEW OFFER.
YOU GET ACCESS TO NURSES WHO
CAN HELP WITH YOUR QUESTIONS.
AND YOUR LOVED ONE CAN GET
EXELON PATCH FREE FOR 30 DAYS.
IF THE DOCTOR FEELS
IT'S RIGHT FOR THEM.
IT CANNOT CHANGE
HOW THE DISEASE PROGRESSES.
HOSPITALIZATION
AND RARELY DEATH
HAVE BEEN REPORTED IN PATIENTS
WHO WORE MORE THAN ONE PATCH
AT A TIME.
THE MOST COMMON SIDE EFFECTS
OF EXELON PATCH
ARE NAUSEA, VOMITING,
AND DIARRHEA.
THE LIKELIHOOD AND SEVERITY
OF THESE SIDE EFFECTS
MAY INCREASE
AS THE DOSE INCREASES.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
LOSS OF APPETITE OR WEIGHT.
PATIENTS WHO WEIGH
LESS THAN 110 POUNDS
MAY EXPERIENCE
MORE SIDE EFFECTS.
PEOPLE AT RISK
FOR STOMACH ULCERS
WHO TAKE CERTAIN
OTHER MEDICINES
SHOULD TALK TO THEIR DOCTOR
BECAUSE SERIOUS
STOMACH PROBLEMS
SUCH AS BLEEDING MAY WORSEN.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
SLOW HEART RATE.
THIRTY DAYS OF EXELON PATCH
FREE FOR YOUR LOVED ONE.
ACCESS TO TRAINED NURSES
FOR YOU.
CALL 1-855-999-1399
OR VISIT EXELONPATCHOFFER2.COM.
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
>>> WE NEEDED TO BE TOGETHER
HERE IN THIS ROOM IN THE
GYMNASIUM, OUTSIDE THE DOORS OF
THIS SCHOOL, LIVING ROOMS AROUND
THE WORLD.
WE NEEDED TO BE TOGETHER TO SHOW
THAT WE ARE TOGETHER AND UNITED.
>> THOSE WORDS FROM THE PASTOR
LAST NIGHT RESONATING NOT ONLY
WITH ME BUT EVERYONE WATCHING
HAD SOMETHING TO FEEL AT THAT
MOMENT AS THOUGH HE WAS SPEAKING
DIRECTLY TO THEM.
IN THIS CRISIS, THERE ARE SO
MANY PEOPLE ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
INDEED AROUND THE WORLD THAT
JUST SOMEHOW WANT THIS COMMUNITY
TO KNOW THAT THEIR HEARTS ARE
WITH THEM.
AND THAT IS REALLY EVIDENT AS
YOU WALK THROUGH THIS TINY TOWN.
YOU CAN SEE YOU CALL IT BEAUT
KWLIND ME.
WHAT YOU CAN'T SEE ARE THE
MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS SPRINGING UP
ALL OVER TOWN.
PEOPLE BRINGING WHATEVER THEY
CAN FROM TEDDY BEARS TO FLOWERS
AND TO TRINKETS, TO HOMEMADE
SIGNS, AND WE SEE IT AT SO MANY
TRAGEDIES BUT WHEN IT COMES TO
20 SMALL CHILDREN, IT JUST HAS A
COMPLETELY DIFFERENT FEEL.
I WANT TO SHOW YOU ONE OF THESE
MEMORIALS I WALKED BY EARLIER
TODAY.
IT DIDN'T TAKE LONG BEFORE THIS
COMMUNITY BEGAN TO START
BRINGING CHRISTMAS TREES TO
WHAT'S BECOME A MAKESHIFT
MEMORIAL NOT FAR FROM THE SCHOOL
AND THERE ARE MORE THAN 20 OF
THESE DECORATED TREES.
EACH ONE WITH STUFFED ANIMALS,
CANDY CANES, BOWS, PLOWERS.
WHAT YOU SEE MOSTLY IS THE
REPETITION OF 20s.
AT LEAST 20.
WHETHER IT IS CANDLES THAT ARE
BROUGHT OUT, BROUGHT OUT IN
COLLECTIONS OF 20, TO REPRESENT
THESE VICTIMS.
YOU ALSO SEE THE FLOWERS THAT
HAVE BEEN BUT OUT FROM LOCAL
MORIE I
FLORISTS.
REMARKABLE THE NUMBER OF TEDDY
BEARS HERE AND STUFFED ANIMALS.
YOU NOTICE UP HERE, ONE OF
THE -- ONE OF THE PERMANENT
PILLARS SOMEONE BROUGHT OUT,
ANGEL WINGS.
THERE IS A SIGN BELOW SAYING WE
PROMISE NEVER TO FORGET YOU.
MOVING A LITTLE FURTHER ON, YOU
SEE THE REAL COLLECTION OF WHERE
THIS MAKESHIFT MEMORIAL STARTED.
A TENT NOW.
BUT EVERYTHING IS SO WET FROM
THE RAIN.
HUNDREDS OF TEDDY BEARS AND
FLOWERS AND MESSAGES AND
CANDLES, ONES THAT ARE STILL
BURN RING NOW UNDER THE TENT.
IF YOU LOOK UP HERE YOU WILL SEE
WHY.
THIS IS THE PERMANENT SIGN FOR
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
JUST BEYOND HERE.
MEDIA IS NOT ALLOWED PAST THIS
POINT NOR IS THE PUBLIC.
THIS IS WHERE PEOPLE CONGREGATED
TO BRING THEIR REMEMBRANCES.
I SPOKE TO MAN WHO LIVES DOWN
THE STREET.
HE WAS SHAKING AS HE PUT A PEW
TEDDY BEARS DOWN.
I ASKED HIM, YOU LIVE HERE.
YOU SEEM SO MOVED BY THIS AND --
IT HAS BEEN THREE DAYS.
HE JUST SAID -- NEEDED A WAY TO
SHOW HOW HE FELT.
JUST CAME BY HIMSELF, TEDDY
BEARS IN HIS BACKPACK.
YOU CAN SEE THE SIGNS
EVERYWHERE.
ANGELS HERE ON THE TREE.
IT IS JUST SO MOVING TO SEE WHAT
PEOPLE HAVE BROUGHT.
OVER HERE, SOMEONE FOLDED --
LOOKS LIKE AT LEAST 20 PIECES OF
ORIGAMI WITH THE NAMES OF THE
VICTIMS.
PRAY ALL THE TIME.
SECURITY GUARDS IN EVERY SCHOOL.
SEE SOME POLITICAL MESSAGES
HERE.
REALLY FOR THE MOST PART JUST
MEMORIES AND THOUGHTS AND LOVE.
HERE YOU CAN SEE THE STARS.
THIS IS GRA
THIS IS GRACE McDONNELL'S STAR.
SHE WAS KILLED IN THE TRAGEDY.
CLEARLY, THERE ARE SO MANY.
JUST REMARKABLE TO EVEN TRY TO
NAME THEM ALL.
DANIEL BARDEN.
COME TO THE END OF THE TREES,
YOU CAN SEE THAT THIS IS JUST
ABOUT THE ONLY WAY RIGHT NOW
OTHER THAN COMING TO THE VIGILS
THAT PEOPLE CAN SOMEHOW, SOMEHOW
SHOW HOW THEY ARE FEELING, HOW
THEY ARE DESTROYED BY THIS AND
SOMEHOW REMEMBER THOSE WHO HAVE
BEEN KILLED.
♪
HEY, LOOK!
A SHOOTING STAR!
MAKE A WISH!
I WISH WE COULD
LIE HERE FOREVER.
I WISH THIS TEST DRIVE WAS OVER,
SO WE COULD HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
TEST DRIVE!
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A JETTA.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN,
$0 DUE AT SIGNING, $0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
>>> I KNOW THAT NEWTOWN WILL
PREVAIL.
THAT WE WILL NOT FALLING TO ACTS
OF VIOLENCE.
IT IS A DEFINING MOMENT FOR OUR
TOWN BUT IT DOES NOT DEFINE US.
WE ARE MUST HAVE TO
WE ARE NEWTOWN, A SPECIAL AND
CARING PLACE.
WE ARE DEFINED BY ACTS OF
COURAGE, BIG ACTS OF LOVE, AND
BY OUR CONTINUING COMMITMENT AND
LOVE FOR OUR CHILDREN AND
FAMILIES.
>> TRISHA LLODRA, LIKE THE MAYOR
IN THIS AREA.
THERE ARE SO MANY IN THIS AREA
OF CONNECTICUT.
JUST A FEW HOURS AGO, NEWS BROKE
THAT IN RIDGEFIELD 20 MINUTES
FROM WHERE I'M STANDING, YET
ANOTHER SCHOOL DISTRICT WENT
INTO LOCKDOWN.
OBVIOUSLY NERVES ARE ON EDGE.
BUT THE REPORT THAT CAME IN
OFFICIALLY WAS THAT SOMEONE WHO
WAS DRIVING BY, NEARBY TRAIN
STATION, SAW SOMEONE WITH WHAT
APPEARED TO BE A GUN, CALLED IT
IN AND THE SCHOOLS IMMEDIATELY
WENT INTO LOCKDOWN.
NOW IT IS OVER NOW.
THE SCHOOLS ARE NOT IN LOCKDOWN
ANYMORE BUT GIVES THANK YOU
FEELING OF HOW NERVOUS EVERYONE
IS.
NOT JUST IN THIS COMMUNITY BUT
IN COMMUNITIES THROUGHOUT
CONNECTICUT.
ALL THE WAY DOWN TO GEORGIA AS
WELL.
MY NEXT GUEST IS CORPORAL JAKE
SMITH FROM THE COUNTY POLICE.
CORPORAL SMITH, I UNDERSTAND
THAT THERE ARE ALL SORTS OF
DIFFERENT SECURITY MEASURES
GOING INTO PLACE IN YOUR AREA AS
WELL AND YOU ARE MANY MILES AND
MANY STATES AWAY.
>> YEAH.
THAT'S CORRECT.
OUR DEPARTMENT MUCH LIKE OTHER
DEPARTMENTS THROUGHOUT THE
COUNTRY HAVE HAD AN ACTION PLAN
IN PLACE FOR RESPONSE TO AN
INCIDENT LIKE THIS.
AND WE HAVE BEEN FORTUNATE
ENOUGH TO NOT HAVE TO ENACT THAT
PLAN IN THE PAST.
WE ARE DOING SO NOW.
THIS IS NOT IN RESPONSE TO ANY
SPECIFIC THREAT.
IT IS AS MUCH AS ANYTHING TO
REASSURE OUR CITIZENS AND THE
PUBLIC IN GWINNETT COUNTY THAT
WE ARE PRESENT.
>> WILL'S JUST -- YOU KNOW,
THERE'S NO TEMPLATE AS SANJAY
GUPTA AND I WERE SAYING EARLIER,
THERE IS NO TEMPLATE TO BASE OUR
FUTURE ACTIONS ON WHEN IT COMES
TO AN EVENT OF THIS MAGNITUDE
HERE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
I HAVE BEEN HEARING THAT AT
LEAST ONE OF THE COUNTIES IN
YOUR IS NOW REQUIRING ALL OF ITS
SCHOOLS TO LOCK THEIR DOORS AT
ALL TIMES.
ALL THE CLASSROOMS.
ALSO THERE ARE EXTRA PARENT
VOLUNTEERS ON HAND AS WELL.
I KNOW YOU SAID IT IS NOT IN
RELATION TO ANY SPECIFIC THREAT
BUT CAN YOU GIVE ME A FEELING AS
TO HOW YOU AND YOUR FORCE ARE
LOOKING AT WHAT'S HAPPENED HERE
AND HOW THAT MAY CHANGE YOUR
PLANNING AND HOW TO PROTECT
SCHOOLS IN YOUR COMMUNITY GOING
FORWARD?
>> SURE.
BASED ON THIS ACTION PLAN, WHAT
WE HAVE DONE AND WILL CONTINUE
TO DO FOR THE NEXT FEW DAYS IS
WE HAVE TAKEN EVERY OFFICER
THAT'S NOT ALREADY ASSIGNED TO
PATROL AND NOT ALREADY
RESPONSIBLE FOR THINGS LIKE
WORKING ACCIDENTS AND RESPONDING
TO 911 CALLS.
WE HAVE TAKEN THEM AND ASSIGNED
THEM TO EACH OF THE 102 SCHOOLS
IN OUR DISTRICT.
WE HAVE AN OFFICER STATIONED AT
EACH SCHOOL AND CONTINUE THE
NEXT THREE DAYS WHEN WE WILL
RE-EVALUATE TODAY AND SEE WHERE
WE STAND AND WHERE THE NATION
STANDS WITH THE REACTION TO THIS
INCIDENT.
>> CORPORAL SMITH, I WANT TO ASK
YOU SOMETHING AND IT IS ON A
SEMI PERSONAL LEVEL BUT HAS TO
DO WITH YOUR PROFESSIONAL
BACKGROUND, TOO.
THIS PERPETRATOR TOOK A
SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPON AND SHOT
HIS WAY IN THROUGH THE SECURITY
SYSTEM.
THE PRINCIPAL HAD JUST
IMPLEMENTED A BRAND-NEW SECURITY
SYSTEM AT THIS SCHOOL.
IT WAS THE SAFE AS ANY SCHOOL
ACROSS THE COUNTRY CAN BE.
THIS AUTOMATIC WEAPON WAS NO --
THERE WAS NO MATCH FOR IT.
AND IN THAT LIGHT, AS YOU LOOK
TO YOUR FUTURE PLANNING AND AS
SCHOOL DISTRICTS AND POLICE
OFFICERS AND POLICE ASSOCIATIONS
ACROSS THIS COUNTRY LOOK TO TRY
TO PROTECT THEIR KIDS, IS
THERE -- IS THERE REALLY
ANYTHING THAT YOU CAN DO WHEN
FACED WITH WEAPONS LIKE THESE
THAT ARE OUT THERE?
>> IT IS A VERY DIFFICULT
QUESTION TO ANSWER.
IT GETS INTO A LOT OF ANGLES
THAT I CAN'T DISCUSS WITH YOU
HERE TODAY.
POLICE DEPARTMENTS AROUND THE
COUNTRY HAVE CHANGED THEIR
POLICIES AND PROCEDURES ON HOW
WE RESPOND TO CERTAIN INCIDENTS
LIKE THIS.
IN THE WAKE OF COLUMBINE, MANY
POLICE DEPARTMENTS WENT TO A
PATROL RIFLE PROGRAM WHERE
POLICE OFFICERS WILL BE ACTUALLY
ARMED WITH MORE SUITABLE WEAPONS
FOR DEALING WITH SOMEONE WHO IS
ARMED AND IN SUCH A WAY.
IT IS A VERY DIFFICULT QUESTION
TO ANSWER WHEN YOU SPEAK ABOUT
SECURING A SILT LIKE THE SCHOOL
OR SHOPPING MALL OR MOVIE
THEATER OR ANYTHING ALONG THOSE
LINES.
IT IS ONE I'M NOT PREPARED TO
ANSWER.
>> OF COURSE, THOSE POLICE OFTEN
GET THE CALL AFTER THOSE WEAPONS
HAVE BEEN DISCHARGED.
SO IT IS -- IT IS NOT SOMETHING
THAT CAN BE DEALT WITH AFTER THE
FACT.
CORPORAL JAKE SMITH, THANK YOU
FOR YOUR TIME.
BEST OF LUCK TO YOU AS YOU
CONTINUE YOUR PLANNING AND OTHER
POLICE LIKE YOU ACROSS THE
COUNTRY WHO MAY BE WATCHING AS
WELL.
>> THANK YOU.
>> I JUST WANT TO LET YOU KNOW
THAT THE NEW NEWTOWN DISTRICT
OFFICIALS ARE MEETING TODAY, AS
EVERYONE EXPECTED THEY WOULD BE,
BUT THERE ARE A COUPLE OF THINGS
THEY NEED TO DECIDE.
THEY IMMEDIATE TO FIGURE OUT HOW
TO GET THOSE CHILDREN FROM SANDY
HOOK, FROM THAT ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, BACK INTO SOME SENSE OF
NORMALCY, BACK TO THE CHALK HILL
ELEMENTARY IN MONROE,
NEIGHBORING SCHOOL THAT'S EMPTY
BUT THAT IS WORKABLE AND HOW
THEY CAN GET BACK INTO THE
CLASSES AND SOMEHOW GET BACK TO
A LIFE THAT THEY I LEFT BEHIND
IF THAT IS AT ALL POSSIBLE.
BACK IN A MOMENT.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS BOB,
A REGULAR GUY
WITH AN IRREGULAR HEARTBEAT.
THE USUAL, BOB?
NOT TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
BOB HAS AFIB:
ATRIAL FIBRILLATION NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
A CONDITION THAT PUTS HIM
AT GREATER RISK FOR A STROKE.
[ GPS ] TURN LEFT.
I DON'T THINK SO.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR YEARS, BOB TOOK WARFARIN,
AND MADE A MONTHLY TRIP TO THE
CLINIC TO GET HIS BLOOD TESTED.
BUT NOT ANYMORE.
BOB'S DOCTOR RECOMMENDED
A DIFFERENT OPTION:
ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
XARELTO® IS THE FIRST AND ONLY
ONCE-A-DAY PRESCRIPTION
BLOOD THINNER
FOR PATIENTS WITH AFIB
NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
THAT DOESN'T REQUIRE
ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING.
LIKE WARFARIN,
XARELTO® IS PROVEN EFFECTIVE
TO REDUCE THE RISK
OF AN AFIB-RELATED STROKE.
THERE IS LIMITED DATA
ON HOW THESE DRUGS COMPARE
WHEN WARFARIN IS WELL MANAGED.
NO ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING
MEANS BOB CAN SPEND HIS
EXTRA TIME HOWEVER HE LIKES.
NEW ZEALAND!
XARELTO®
IS JUST ONE PILL A DAY,
TAKEN WITH THE EVENING MEAL.
AND WITH
NO DIETARY RESTRICTIONS,
BOB CAN EAT THE HEALTHY FOODS
HE LIKES.
DO NOT STOP TAKING
XARELTO® RIVAROXABAN
WITHOUT TALKING TO THE DOCTOR
WHO PRESCRIBES IT FOR YOU.
STOPPING MAY INCREASE YOUR RISK
OF HAVING A STROKE.
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU DEVELOP ANY SIGNS
OR SYMPTOMS OF BLEEDING,
LIKE UNUSUAL BRUISING
OR TINGLING.
YOU MAY HAVE A HIGHER RISK
OF BLEEDING
IF YOU TAKE XARELTO®
WITH ASPIRIN PRODUCTS,
NSAIDS OR BLOOD THINNERS.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE TAKING XARELTO®
IF YOU CURRENTLY HAVE
ABNORMAL BLEEDING.
XARELTO® CAN CAUSE BLEEDING,
WHICH CAN BE SERIOUS,
AND RARELY MAY LEAD TO DEATH.
YOU ARE LIKELY TO BRUISE
MORE EASILY ON XARELTO®,
AND IT MAY TAKE LONGER
FOR BLEEDING TO STOP.
TELL YOUR DOCTORS
YOU ARE TAKING XARELTO®
BEFORE ANY PLANNED MEDICAL
OR DENTAL PROCEDURES.
BEFORE STARTING XARELTO®,
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ANY CONDITIONS,
SUCH AS KIDNEY, LIVER
OR BLEEDING PROBLEMS.
READY TO CHANGE YOUR ROUTINE?
ASK YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
FOR MORE INFORMATION
INCLUDING COST SUPPORT OPTIONS,
CALL 1-888-XARELTO
OR VISIT GOXARELTO.COM.
WITH ODOR FREE ASPERCREME.
POWERFUL MEDICINE
RELIEVES PAIN FAST,
WITH NO ODOR.
SO ALL YOU NOTICE IS RELIEF.
ASPERCREME.
♪
>>> EACH TIME THE DAY GETS A
LITTLE LONGER, I WILL THINK AND
DREAM OF THE LIVES THAT MIGHT
HAVE BEEN AND THE LIVES THAT
WERE SO FULL OF GRACE.
AND WHEN THE FLOWERS START TO
COME OUT OF THE GROUND AND WHEN
THEY RISE UP, I WILL KNOW THAT
WE ARE IN TOUCH WITH THOSE THAT
WE HAVE LOST IN THE LAST FEW
DAYS.
>> THE LIVES THAT WERE SO FULL
OF GOOD.
AS REMEMBERED BY THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT, DAN MALLOY.
SPEAKING LAST NIGHT AT THAT
TRIBUTE THAT WAS HELD HERE WHERE
THE PRESIDENT ATTENDED AS WELL.
ONE OF THOSE LIVES, THE
PRINCIPAL OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG.
THE PEOPLE THAT KNOW HER BEST
THAT CAN TELL YOU ABOUT HER WERE
HER FAMILY.
THEY WERE KIND ENOUGH TO LET
GARY TUCHMAN SPEAK WITH THEM
ABOUT THEIR LOSS.
>> Reporter: PRINCIPAL
HOCHSPRUNG WAS QUITE A BIT
YOUNGER THAN HER HUSBAND,
GEORGE.
WHEN THEY GOT MARRIED TEN YEARS
AGO, BOTH FOR THE SECOND TIME,
SHE WITH WOULD DAUGHTERS AND HE
WITH THREE, GEORGE WAS MARRYING
HIS BOSS.
>> SHE WAS ASSISTANT PRINCIPAL
AT OUR SCHOOL.
I WAS A SEVENTH GRADE MATH
TEACHER AT THAT TIME.
AND -- I JUST FELL IN LOVE WITH
HER.
>> Reporter: GEORGE MADE THE BIG
DECISION.
THE TIME HAD COME TO PROPOSE.
>> SHE TURNED ME DOWN FIVE
TIMES.
>> Reporter: YOU ASKED HER TO
MARRY HER BUT SHE TURNED YOU
DOWN.
>> FIVE TIMES.
>> Reporter: WHAT HAPPENED THE
SIXTH TIME?
>> SIXTH TIME -- IT WASN'T SUCH
ROUGH SAILING.
>> Reporter: INDEED.
GEORGE HAD BEEN POPPING THE
QUESTION ON A SAILBOAT THEY
BOUGHT TOGETHER.
>> WE GOT MARRIED OUT OF MYSTIC.
>> Reporter: BETH AND AIM ARE
HIS DATERS FROM THE FIRST
MARRIAGE.
ERICA IS DAWN'S DAUGHTER FROM
HER FIRST MARRIAGE.
HER OTHER DAUGHTER TINA WAS OUT
WHILE WE WERE AT THE HOUSE.
THEY ARE A BLENDED BUT VERY
CLOSE FAMILY WITH 11
GRANDCHILDREN.
>> DAWN AND I BUILT THIS
BEAUTIFUL NEWS THE ADIRONDACKS.
OUR DREAM.
THE DREAM WAS CHRONOLOGICAL
DREAM.
IT WAS GOING TO BE DAWN'S HOUSE,
I WOULD DIE.
I'M MUCH OLDER THAN DAWN.
IT WAS GOING TO BE DAWN'S HOUSE.
DAWN'S CHILDREN, ALL THESE
CHILDREN CAN USE THE HOUSE ON
THE LAKE AND IT WOULD BE
WONDERFUL.
WE BUILT -- DOWNSTAIRS FOR KIDS.
IT WAS GOING TO BE DAWN'S HOUSE
ULTIMATELY WITH ALL THE
CHILDREN, ALL THE CHILDREN.
NOW IT IS ME.
I DON'T THINK I CAN DO THAT.
>> Reporter: I WANT TO REITERATE
YOU HAVE THESE BEAUTIFUL
DAUGHTERS, SON-IN-LAWS,
GRANDCHILDREN, EVERYONE WILL BE
HERE TO TAKE CARE OF YOU.
IS THAT RIGHT, LADIES?
>> YES.
>> MY JOB HAS ALWAYS BEEN TO
TAKE CARE OF OTHER PEOPLE.
>> Reporter: IT IS ALL RIGHT IF
SOME PEOPLE TAKE CARE OF YOU FOR
A WHILE.
>> Reporter: GEORGE TAUGHT AT
MIDDLE SCHOOL WHERE THEY MET.
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE DAY FRIDAY,
THIS IS HOW GEORGE FOUND OUT
WHAT HAPPENED.
>> THE KIDS CAME UP -- WITH A
COMPUTER AND SAID -- SOMETHING
IS HAPPENING AT SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL.
YOUR WIFE HAS BEEN KILLED.
>> Reporter: GEORGE RACED OUT OF
SCHOOL INTO A NIGHTMARE.
LIKE ALL THE FAMILIES OF
VICTIMS, THEY WANT TO KNOW MORE.
ON THIS DAY THEY HAVE LEARNED
MORE.
WOULD TEACHERS SURVIVED TOLD
GEORGE THEY WERE HAVING A
MEETING WITH DAWN WHEN THE SHOTS
STARTED RINGING OUT.
>> DAWN PUT HERSELF IN JEOPARDY.
I HAVE BEEN ANGRY ABOUT THAT,
ANGRY, MILLION JUST NOW TODAY
WHEN I MET THE TWO WOMEN THAT
SHE TOLD TO GO RUN TO SHELTER
WHILE SHE ACTUALLY CONFRONTED
THE GUNMAN AND SHE COULD NOT --
SHE COULD HAVE AVOIDED THAT.
SHE DIDN'T.
I KNEW SHE WOULDN'T.
I'M NOT ANGRY
I'M NOT ANGRY.
I'M NOT ANGRY ANYMORE.
I'M JUST VERY SAD.
THEY WERE AT THE MEETING.
THERE WERE GUNSHOTS.
SOMEBODY SHOT THE WINDOW.
SOMEBODY CAME IN, INTO THE --
NOT INTO THE OFFICE BUT INTO THE
BUILDING, THE FOYER OF THE
BUILDING, TOLD US TO GO HIDE.
AND SHE AND AT LEAST ONE OTHER
TEACHER RAN OUT AND ACTUALLY
TRIED TO SUBDUE THE KILLER.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE THAT COMES
FROM.
DAWN WAS 5'2".
>> Reporter: EVERYONE HERE IS SO
PROUD.
NO ONE MORE SO THAN ERICA WHO
SAID HER MOM WAS ALWAYS THERE
FOR HER DAUGHTERS.
>> EVERY GAME SHE WAS THERE,
EVERY PRACTICE SHE WAS THERE,
ALL OF MY SISTERS' CHEERLEADING
STUFF SHE WAS THERE, EVERY DANCE
COMPETITION, SHE WAS DOING
HOMEWORK ON THE BLEACHERS, BUT
SHE WAS THERE.
AND SHE WAS MY ROCK.
MY ROCK.
>> Reporter: AND NOW SHE IS A
HERO, TOO.
THE FINAL THING I WANT TO ASK
YOU IS, WHAT WOULD YOU SAY TO
YOUR MOM RIGHT NOW?
>> COME BACK.
PLEASE COME BACK.
I GAVE BIRTH TO MY DAUGHTER
ON MAY 18TH,
FIVE DAYS LATER,
I HAD A MASSIVE HEART ATTACK.
BAYER ASPIRIN WAS THE FIRST
THING THE EMTS GAVE ME.
NOW, I'M ON
A BAYER ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Male Announcer ] BE SURE
TO TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE YOU BEGIN
AN ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Woman ]
LEARN FROM MY STORY.
>> Reporter: THE PRESIDENT LEFT
THE COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, LAST NIGHT TO HEAD
BACK TO WASHINGTON, AND
OBVIOUSLY HE HAS A LOT OF
PRESSING BUSINESS IN WASHINGTON
AS WELL.
WE HAVE BREAKING NEWS OUT OF THE
WHITE HOUSE.
I WANT TO TAKE YOU NOW TO MY
COLLEAGUE, DAN LOTHIAN, WHO'S
COVERING FOR ME DOWN THERE.
EXACTLY WHAT'S HAPPENING, DAN?
>> Reporter: WELL, WE HAVE
LEARNED FROM A WHITE HOUSE
OFFICIAL THAT PRESIDENT OBAMA IS
MEETING HERE AT THE WHITE HOUSE
WITH HOUSE SPEAKER BOEHNER TO
DISCUSS THE FISCAL CLIFF
NEGOTIATIONS.
AS YOU KNOW, THERE HAVE BEEN
PHONE CALLS, AND THERE'S BEEN A
LOT OF OPTIMISM IN RECENT DAYS
BECAUSE OF SOME WILLINGNESS,
APPARENTLY, TO COMPROMISE ON THE
PART OF REPUBLICANS.
AND SO THIS MEETING TAKING PLACE
WITHIN THE HOUR HERE AT THE
WHITE HOUSE.
IT'S UNCLEAR WHETHER WHAT WE'RE
SEEING HERE IS THE LAST FEW
MINUTES BEFORE A FORMAL
AGREEMENT IS REACHED OR STILL
SOME TOUGH ISSUES TO WORK OUT.
BUT WHAT I CAN CONFIRM IS THAT
SPEAKER BOEHNER AND THE
PRESIDENT MEETING HERE AT THE
WHITE HOUSE TO DISCUSS THOSE
ONGOING NEGOTIATIONS TO AVOID
THE FISCAL CLIFF.
>> Reporter: ALL RIGHT, DAN
LOTHIAN FOR US.
THANK YOU.
I WANT TO GO OVER TO CAPITOL
HILL NOW WHERE OUR SENIOR
CONGRESSIONAL CORRESPONDENT,
DANA BASH, IS ALSO FOLLOWING THE
DEVELOPMENTS.
WHAT CAN YOU ADD?
>> Reporter: WE CAN ADD SOME
INTERESTING NEW DETAILS ABOUT
WHERE THE DISCUSSIONS ARE.
THIS MOSTLY COMES FROM EXCELLENT
REPORTING FROM OUR CONGRESSIONAL
PRODUCER, DEIRDRE WALSH.
AND THAT IS ROUGHLY A $2
TRILLION FRAMEWORK.
THIS IS SOMETHING THAT
REPUBLICANS ARE PUSHING THE
CONVERSATIONS RIGHT NOW.
$2 TRILLION.
ABOUT $1 TRILLION IN NEW TAX
REVENUE, ABOUT $1 TRILLION IN
SPENDING CUTS.
I WANT TO EMPHASIZE SOURCES IN
BOTH PARTIES MADE CLEAR THAT
THIS IS SOMETHING THAT
REPUBLICANS ARE PUSHING NOW.
THE BIG QUESTION, WHEN YOU TALK
ABOUT THE OVERALL POTENTIAL DEAL
ON THIS ESPECIALLY, I'M TOLD
FROM DEMOCRATIC SOURCES IS
WHETHER OR NOT THE SPENDING
SIDE, $1 TRILLION IN SPENDING
CUTS, IS SOMETHING THAT CAN PASS
THE HOUSE AND THE SENATE,
SPECIFICALLY BECAUSE WHAT
THEY'RE TALKING ABOUT IS A LOT
OF CUTS TO MEDICARE.
AND THAT IS SOMETHING THE
DEMOCRATS HAVE RESISTED.
SO THIS IS STILL FLUID.
YOU KNOW WHAT, ASHLEIGH?
AS WE'RE TALKING, I'M TOLD THAT
THE MEETING JUST CONCLUDED.
IT LASTED 45 MINUTES.
SO HOPEFULLY WE'LL GET A LITTLE
MORE DETAIL.
JUST THE FACT THAT THEY'RE
TALKING FACE TO FACE IS A GOOD
SIGN.
>> Reporter: AND OBVIOUSLY THE
BUSINESS OF WASHINGTON
CONTINUES.
VERY MUCH APPRECIATED, DANA
BASH, FOR FOLLOWING THAT FOR US.
JUST WANT TO WRAP UP FROM HERE
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, IF I
CAN.
THERE WILL BE TWO FUNERALS
TAKING PLACE FOR TWO OF THE
6-YEAR-OLD CHILDREN, LITTLE JACK
PINTO AND NOAH POZNER WILL BE
BURIED TODAY.
ALSO NO SCHOOL FOR ANY OF THE
CHILDREN IN THIS DISTRICT.
AND THEY'LL BE RETURNING
TOMORROW.
BUT NOT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
THEY WILL NOT BE RETURNING.
THERE ARE ALTERNATE PLANS BEING
MADE FOR THEM.
THE VIGILS CONTINUE ALMOST
AROUND THE CLOCK.
AND THERE IS WORD OF A STATEWIDE
VIGIL BEING PLANNED AS WELL.
MORE INFORMATION ON THAT TO BE
ANNOUNCED.
AND THE INVESTIGATION,
OBVIOUSLY, CONTINUES.
THE BIGGEST QUESTION TO BE
ANSWERED, WHY?
I'M ASHLEIGH BANFIELD REPORTING.
"CNN NEWSROOM" CONTINUES AFTER
THIS BREAK.
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU ARE A BUSINESS PRO.
EXECUTOR OF EFFICIENCY.
YOU CAN SPOT AN AMATEUR
FROM A MILE AWAY...
WHILE GOING SHOELESS
AND METAL-FREE IN SECONDS.
AND YOU...RENT FROM National.
BECAUSE ONLY National
LETS YOU CHOOSE ANY CAR
IN THE AISLE...AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE A FULL-SIZE
OR ABOVE,
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
NOW THIS...WILL WORK.
[ Male Announcer ]
JUST LIKE YOU, BUSINESS PRO.
JUST LIKE YOU.
GO National.
GO LIKE A PRO.
YOU WON'T JUST
FIND US ONLINE,
YOU'LL ALSO FIND US IN PERSON,
WITH DEDICATED SUPPORT TEAMS
AT OVER 500 BRANCHES
NATIONWIDE.
SO WHEN YOU CALL OR VISIT,
YOU CAN ASK FOR A NAME
YOU KNOW.
BECAUSE PERSONAL SERVICE
STARTS WITH A REAL PERSON.
[ Rodger ]
AT SCOTTRADE,
SEVEN DOLLAR TRADES
ARE JUST THE START.
OUR SUPPORT TEAMS
ARE NEARBY,
READY TO HELP.
IT'S NO WONDER SO MANY INVESTORS
ARE SAYING...
[ All ]
I'M WITH SCOTTRADE.