THAT THOSE PARENTS WHO WERE NOT
REUNITED WITH THEIR CHILDREN
THEY KNOW THAT THOSE CHILDRENS
BODIES ARE STILL IN THE SCHOOL
TONIGHT.
THOSE TEACHERS, THOSE ADULTS WHO
WERE ALSO SHOT, THE SIX OF THEM,
THEIR BODIES ARE ALSO IN THE
SCHOOL TONIGHT.
POSITIVE IDENTIFICATIONS HAVE TO
BE DONE.
THE CORONER'S OFFICE HAS A HUGE
TASK.
THE INVESTIGATION OF THE SHOTS.
OVER 100 ROUNDS BY ONE
ESTIMATION.
THERE IS A MASSIC FORENSIC
PROJECT UNDER WAY AND AT THE
SAME TIME A MASSIVE EMOTIONAL
PROJECT FOR THIS COMMUNITY IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT TO SOMEHOW
HEAL AS WE HEAD IN TO THE
HOLIDAYS HOLIDAYS ACROSS
THIS COUNTRY.
PIERS MORGAN STARTS NOW.
>>> BREAKING NEWS.
LIVE AT A COMMUNITY IN MORNING
AFTER THE WORTH MASS SHOOTING IN
AMERICAN HISTORY.
A GUNMAN WALKED INTO
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT AND OPENED
FIRE.
HE KILLED 20 CHILDREN, YOUNG
CHILDREN FROM 5 TO 10 YEARS OLD.
THE SHOOTINGS TOOK PLACE IN TWO
ROOMS OF ONE SECTION OF THE
SCHOOL AND HE KILLED AT LEAST
SIX ADULTS BEFORE KILLING
HIMSELF.
POLICE FOUND THE BODY OF THE
SUSPECT'S MOTHER IN HIS HOME
EARLIER IN THE DAY.
A PRAYER VIGIL WAS HELD IN A
CHURCH AND TOOK PLACE A MILE
AWAY FROM THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
HUNDREDS WERE IN ATTENDANCE.
AT THE WHITE HOUSE A VIGIL WAS
HELD WITH PEOPLE GATHERING FOR
MORE GUN CONTROL.
MANY SAY IT DEMANDS TOUGHER
LEGISLATION.
IN THE WHITE HOUSE, A
VISIBLY SHAKEN PRESIDENT OBAMA
OFFERED THESE WORDS ABOUT THE
MASS KILLING.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS.
MEN AND WOMEN WHO DEVOTED THEIR
LIVES TO HELPING OUR CHILDREN
FULFILL THEIR DREAMS.
>> HIGHLY EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT
OBAMA REFLECTING HOW MOST OF THE
NATION WOULD HAVE BEEN FEELING
AND TONIGHT POLICE HAVE
IDENTIFIED THE KILLER AS ADAM
LANZA.
THIS IS HIS BROTHER RYAN LANZA
BEING TAKEN INTO QUESTIONING.
MUCH MORE ON THE SHOOTER AHEAD.
I'LL TALK TO HIS FORMER
CLASSMATE.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI HAS NEW DETAILS
FROM OUTSIDE THE SCHOOL.
A DESPERATE DAY FOR THE SCHOOL
AND THE FAMILIES OF THE POOR
CHILDREN AND FOR AMERICA.
WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT THE PERSON
WHO PERPETRATED THE HIDEOUS
CRIME?
>> Reporter: YOU KNOW, IT IS SO
HEARTBREAKING, PIERS.
WE ARE LEARNING HE IS
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA.
WE KNOW ACCORDING TO OUR SOURCES
THAT FOR WHATEVER REASON WHEN HE
CAME TO THE SCHOOL THIS DAY, HE
WAS WEARING WHAT IS DESCRIBED TO
ME AS BLACK BATTLE FATIGUES AND
A MILITARY VEST.
HE CAME ARMED WITH THREE
WEAPONS.
TWO OF THEM HANDGUNS.
ONE AS A GLOCK AND ANOTHER AS A
SIG SAUER AND A THIRD POLICE
FOUND IN THE VEHICLE.
THE TWO WEAPONS WERE FOUND ON
HIM IN THE SCHOOL.
THE THIRD WAS FOUND, THE
BUSHMASTER WHICH IS A SEMI
AUTOMATIC WAS FOUND IN A CAR
OUTSIDE THE SCHOOL.
WHAT LED HIM TO THIS?
WE DON'T KNOW.
WE DO KNOW THIS.
POLICE HAVE QUESTIONED BOTH HIS
BROTHER AND HIS FATHER.
HIS BROTHER WAS TAKEN INTO
CUSTODY FOR QUESTIONING ONLY.
HE IS NOT BEING CALLED A
SUSPECT.
FROM HIS APARTMENT IN HOBOKEN,
NEW JERSEY.
WE UNDERSTAND THE FATHER WAS
ALSO QUESTIONED BY AUTHORITIES
HERE IN THE NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
AREA.
THE FATHER IS DIVORCED FROM
NANCY LANZA.
SHE IS THE MOTHER OF THE TWO WHO
IS A SCHOOLTEACHER AND COUNTED
AMONG THE DEAD.
HER BODY WAS FOUND IN A
RESIDENCE HERE IN THE NEWTOWN
AREA, AS WELL.
BELIEVE IT OR NOT, PIERS, THE
WEAPONS ACCORDING TO AUTHORITIES
WERE OWNED BY THE MOTHER, NANCY
LANZA IN THIS CASE.
NOT BY THE SHOOTER.
STILL TRYING TO PIECE TOGETHER A
MOTIVE.
THERE ARE SIGNS WE ARE HEARING
FROM OUR SOURCES THAT THE
SHOOTER MAY HAVE SUFFERED FROM
SOME KIND OF PERSONALITY
DISORDER.
DID HE LEAVE NOTES BEHIND?
DID HE TELL ANYONE WHAT HE WAS
PLANNING TO DO?
AMONG THE MANY QUESTIONS THAT WE
ALL HAVE TONIGHT.
>> SUSAN CANDIOTTI, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH INDEED.
I WANT TO TURN TO ASHLEIGH
BANFIELD.
SHE'S IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT AS
WELL.
I WAS WATCHING WHEN YOU WERE
SPEAKING TO WOLF BLITZER AND YOU
BECAME VERY EMOTIONAL.
TWO OF YOUR CHILDREN WENT TO
SCHOOL IN CONNECTICUT AND YOU
WERE NOT SURE WHAT WAS HAPPENING
WITH THEM.
THANKFULLY THEY WERE OKAY.
BUT THIS IS EVERY PARENT'S
NIGHTMARE.
FROM WHAT WE UNDERSTAND THE
BODIES OF THESE POOR CHILDREN
ARE STILL LYING THERE ON
WHAT THE POLICE ARE CALLING THE
CRIME SCENE OF THE SCHOOL.
THE PARENTS CAN'T EVEN SEE THEM.
IT'S AN UNIMAGINABLE HORROR.
>> Reporter: THERE IS NO OTHER
WAY TO PUT IT.
UNIMAGINABLE HORROR AND AN EVIL
VISITED UPON THE COMMUNITY
ACCORDING TO THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT WHO SPOKE HERE
EARLIER.
ANOTHER DETAIL FOR YOU THAT I
WANT TO SHARE ABOUT HOW SOME OF
THESE PARENTS LEARNED THEY
WOULDN'T BE SEEING THEIR
CHILDREN AGAIN.
I THINK YOU ALREADY KNOW THE
DETAIL THAT MANY OF THE CHILDREN
WERE RUSHED OUT OF THE SCHOOL.
OUT OF THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
BY THE POLICE AND TEACHERS AND
RACED ON FOOT TO A NEARBY FIRE
STATION WHICH BECAME THE STAGING
AREA.
THERE WERE ROBOCALLS THAT WENT
OUT.
WE HEARD THE ROBOCALLS SAYING
PARENTS OF THE SANDY HOOK
STUDENTS, COME TO THIS FIRE
STATION TO BE REUNITED WITH YOUR
CHILDREN.
THROUGHOUT THE DAY THERE WAS ONE
AREA WITHIN THAT FIRE STATION
WHERE THE CHILDREN WERE KEPT AND
THEY WERE SHOWN MOVIES UNTIL
THEIR PARENTS COULD COME AND
FIND THEM.
THERE WAS ANOTHER AREA WHERE A
NUMBER OF THE PARENTS WERE
MILLING ABOUT, WAITING FOR
STUDENTS TO BE BROUGHT INTO THE
FIRE STATION.
YOU CAN IMAGINE IT WAS A CHAOTIC
SCENE FOR SOMETIME.
SLOWLY BUT SURELY OVER THE
COURSE OF THE DAY PARENTS
ARRIVED AND CHILDREN WERE TAKEN
AWAY AND PARENTS CONTINUED TO
WAIT AND OTHER CHILDREN DIDN'T
ARRIVE AND ULTIMATELY THERE WAS
A MOMENT WHERE THEY HAD TO TELL
THE WAITING PARENTS THERE WILL
BE NO MORE REUNIONS TONIGHT.
I'M TOLD FROM SOMEONE WHO WAS
INSIDE THAT AREA IN A ROOM
ADJACENT THAT AT THE MOMENT THE
PARENTS WERE TOLD THERE WOULD BE
NO MORE CHILDREN COMING THERE
WERE WAILS THAT WERE RELEASED.
THE PERSON WHO TOLD ME THIS SHE
SAID SHE COMPLETELY BROKE DOWN.
THERE WAS A NURSE ON HAND WHO
VOLUNTEERED HAVING WORKED TWO
DECADES IN THE BUSINESS.
HER BROTHER TELLING ME THAT SHE
JUST WANTED TO BE THERE AND HELP
IN ANY WAY SHE COULD AS A GRIEF
COUNSELLOR AND WAS PRESENT AT
THAT TIME AS WELL.
A HORRIFYING MOMENT IF YOU CAN
IMAGINE BEING THOSE PARENTS WHO
IS WAITED AND WAITED AND WAITED
ONLY TO HEAR THIS AND ULTIMATELY
LIKE YOU SAID, THEY KNOW THE
BODIES OF THEIR CHILDREN ARE
STILL IN THAT SCHOOL TONIGHT.
>> IT'S HARD TO IMAGINE ANYTHING
WORSE IN THE WORLD.
THANK YOU FOR NOW.
I WILL BE JOINED BY THE MAYOR OF
DANBURY RIGHT NEXT TO NEWTOWN.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING ME.
THIS IS ALMOST BEYOND
DESCRIPTION, BEYOND ANY
UNDERSTANDING.
HOW IS THE COMMUNITY DEALING
WITH THIS OR ARE THEY?
WHAT CAN YOU DO?
>> WELL, OBVIOUSLY IT'S BEEN A
HORRIFIC DAY IN THE GREATER
DANBURY AREA AND PARTICULARLY
THE TOWN OF NEWTOWN.
OUR HEART GOES OUT TO THE
INDIVIDUALS WHO LOST LOVED ONES
TODAY AND OBVIOUSLY THE CHILDREN
AND THE STAFF AND EVERYBODY
ELSE.
IT'S BEEN AN INCREDIBLY
DIFFICULT DAY.
I HAVE TO TELL YOU THAT WE'RE
DOING WHAT NEEDS TO BE DONE.
THE FIRST RESPONDERS WERE
TREMENDOUS AND THE STAFF HAVE
BEEN HEROIC IN TERMS OF THEIR
APPROACH TO THIS.
IT'S AN ABSOLUTE INTERNATIONAL
TRAGEDY AND CRISIS.
>> I UNDERSTAND THAT YOU KNEW
THE PRINCIPAL OF THE SCHOOL WHO
ALSO WAS KILLED.
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
I HAD THE HONOR OF WORKING IN
THE SAME SCHOOL SYSTEM AND VERY
CLOSE PROXIMITY TO DAWN WHO
PASSED AWAY TODAY.
SHE WAS A TEACHER IN THE SCHOOL
SYSTEM AND ELEVATED UP THROUGH
THE RANKS AND ENDED UP THE
PRINCIPAL HERE IN NEWTOWN.
A COMMITTED, HARDWORKING AND
DEDICATED EDUCATOR.
SOMEONE WHO CARED DEEPLY ABOUT
THE KIDS AND PUT KIDS FIRST IN
EVERY FACET AND EVERY WAY IN
WHICH SHE EXECUTED HER JOB AND
SOMEBODY WHO WE ALL ADMIRED
WORKING WITH HER CHILDREN AS A
PROFESSIONAL.
>> EXTREMELY SAD DAY AND I
APPRECIATE YOU JOINING ME.
I CAN ONLY WISH YOU THE VERY
BEST.
AS YOU'RE TRYING TO REBUILD THE
COMMUNITY.
DID YOU KNOW IF THERE PLANS FOR
MORE VIGILS TOMORROW?
>> THERE ARE VIGILS SCHEDULED
THROUGHOUT THE WEEKEND.
IN ADDITION TO THAT, CONNECTICUT
ITSELF IS HAVING A SIMULTANEOUS
VIGIL THAT THEY ARE TRYING TO
ORGANIZE RIGHT NOW WHERE EACH
TOWN AND VILLAGE AND CITY WILL
TAKE A MOMENT OUT AND SPEND TIME
REFLECTING AND MAYBE STARTING
ONCE WE GET THROUGH THIS INITIAL
SHOCK AND REFLECTING A LITTLE
BIT ABOUT OUR PUBLIC POLICY
POSITIONS IN TERMS OF THINGS
LIKE GUN CONTROL AND HOW WE DEAL
WITH FOLKS WHO ARE MENTALLY
DISABLED.
ONCE WE UNDERSTAND THIS HORRIFIC
TRAGEDY THAT OCCURRED.
I THINK THAT CONVERSATION WILL
BE STARTED OVER THE NEXT COUPLE
OF WEEKS.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH INDEED
FOR JOINING ME.
>> THANK YOU, PIERS.
>> WE CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT IT WAS
LIKE IN THE SCHOOL.
SOFIA WAS THERE AND JUST 8 YEARS
OLD.
SHE'S A STUDENT AT SANDY HOOK.
SHE JOINS ME NOW WITH HER
MOTHER, BRENDA.
THANK YOU BOTH FOR JOINING ME.
IF I MAY START WITH YOU, BRENDA.
THIS IS EVERY MOTHER'S
NIGHTMARE.
WHEN WAS THE FIRST YOU HEARD
ABOUT THIS AND HOW DID YOU HEAR?
>> I RECEIVED A CALL FROM THE
SCHOOL SYSTEM FROM THE
SUPERINTENDENT SAYING THAT THERE
WAS A SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN, BUT
DIDN'T SAY IT WAS A SCHOOL.
THAT THE SCHOOLS WERE ON
LOCKDOWN.
I WASN'T TOO CONCERNED BECAUSE I
DIDN'T KNOW WHERE IT HAPPENED.
I RECEIVED A TEXT ON MY PHONE
FROM A NEWS ORGANIZATION AND
THEY SAID THAT SANDY HOOK SCHOOL
HAD A SHOOTING.
I GOT IN MY CAR AND I WENT OVER
TO THE SCHOOL AND THERE WERE
ALREADY STATE POLICE AND THE
FIRE AND NEWTOWN POLICE.
>> WHEN YOU GOT THERE, OBVIOUSLY
SCENES OF COMPLETE CHAOS, HOW
QUICKLY WAS IT THAT YOU REALIZED
YOUR DAUGHTER WAS SAFE?
>> OKAY.
WHEN I GOT THERE, THERE WAS
COMPLETE CHAOS, BUT I DID SEE
MOMS AND A NEIGHBOR AND ASKED
THEM WHAT HAPPENED AND THEY SAID
THEY DIDN'T KNOW.
THAT THERE WAS A SHOOTING AND I
SAW A NEIGHBOR LIKE I SAID AND
HE SAID THEY CARRIED OUT A
LITTLE GIRL AND SHE
LOOKED LIKE SHE WAS DEAD.
INSTANTLY I PANICKED BECAUSE OF
MY BABY HERE, BUT THANKFULLY NO
SOONER HE SAID THAT I LOOKED
TOWARDS THE KIDS BEING BROUGHT
FROM THE SCHOOL TO THE FIREHOUSE
AND I SAW HER CLASS AND I RAN UP
AND I SAID WHERE IS SOFIA AND
THEY SAID SHE IS OKAY.
SHE'S COMING.
I SAW HER WITH HER TEACHER AND
WE ALL WERE TAKEN INTO THE
FIREHOUSE AND KEPT SO THEY COULD
DO A ROLL CALL AND MAKE SURE ALL
THE STUDENTS WERE ACCOUNTED FOR.
>> SOFIA, IT'S BEEN A TERRIFYING
DAY FOR YOU AND YOUR FRIENDS.
WHAT DID YOU THINK WAS
HAPPENING?
WERE YOU AWARE SOMEBODY WAS
FIRING A GUN IN THE SCHOOL?
>> CAN YOU HEAR, HONEY?
>> NOT REALLY.
>> SHE CAN'T REALLY HEAR.
SHE TOLD ME THAT THEY HEARD POPS
IN THE HALLWAY.
THE TEACHER TOLD ME ALSO,
COURTNEY MARTIN IS MY HERO, SHE
LOCKED THE DOOR IMMEDIATELY AND
BROUGHT ALL THE KIDS TO A CORNER
OF THE ROOM WHERE THEY STAYED
THERE.
THEY WERE SCARED AND SHAKEN, BUT
THEY DIDN'T KNOW WHAT WAS GOING
ON UNTIL LATER WHEN THEY WERE
BROUGHT INTO THE FIREHOUSE.
POLICE CAME AND KNOCKED ON THE
DOOR AND SAID IT'S OKAY, YOU CAN
COME OUT.
THEY GUIDED THEM TO THE BACK OF
THE SCHOOL AND THEY WALKED OVER
TO THE FIREHOUSE.
THAT'S WHERE I CAUGHT UP WITH
SOFIA.
>> HOW IS SOPHIA NOW?
IT MUST HAVE BEEN A TRAUMATIC
EXPERIENCE FOR ALL THE CHILDREN
WHO SURVIVED THIS.
>> I THINK SHE IS NUMB RIGHT
NOW.
SHE IS A PRETTY BRIGHT KID AND
SHE HAS A BIG SUPPORT STAFF AT
HOME AND WE LOVE HER VERY MUCH
AND SHE WILL BE FINE.
WE ARE DEVASTATED FOR THE REST
OF THE FAMILIES.
WE DON'T KNOW WHO WAS HURT.
I DO KNOW MY CLOSE FRIENDS'S
CHILDREN ARE OKAY, BUT WE DON'T
KNOW WHO THE CHILDREN WERE.
>> I DON'T KNOW IF SHE CAN HEAR
ME OR NOT, BUT I WONDERED IF SHE
WANTED TO SAY ANYTHING ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED TO HER TODAY.
>> DO YOU WANT TO SAY ANYTHING,
HONEY?
ARE YOU SURE?
I THINK SHE'S TOO COLD NOW.
>> SHE SHOULD PROBABLY GO HOME
WITH HER MOM.
IT'S BEEN A TERRIFYING DAY FOR
EVERYBODY INVOLVED.
I AM SO GRATEFUL THAT YOU WERE
ABLE TO SEE YOUR DAUGHTER.
OBVIOUSLY YOUR HEART MUST GO OUT
TO THE POOR FAMILIES WHO HAVE
NOT BEEN ABLE TO SEE THEIR POOR
CHILDREN AGAIN.
>> IT'S A SMALL COMMUNITY AND
IT'S A CLOSE-KNIT SCHOOL AND
DEVASTATING.
I WILL BE HERE FOR ANYBODY AND
OUR PRAYERS GO OUT TO ALL THE
FAMILIES.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH INDEED.
>> I'M JUST THE LUCKIEST LADY
RIGHT NOW.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH INDEED
FOR JOINING ME.
I APPRECIATE IT.
>> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> VERY LUCKY INDEED.
THE GUNMAN IS ADAM LANZA AND
JOINING ME IS LANZA'S FORMER
CLASSMATE, ALEX ISRAEL.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING ME.
YOU KNEW THIS CHARACTER.
IS THIS SOMETHING YOU COULD HAVE
PREDICTED HE WOULD ONE DAY FLIP
AND DO SOMETHING AS MONSTEROUS
AS THIS?
>> I DON'T KNOW IF YOU CAN EVER
PREDICT SOMETHING LIKE THAT
WOULD HAPPEN.
YOU NEVER THINK IT'S GOING TO
HAPPEN TO YOUR SCHOOL AND WHERE
YOU LIVED YOUR WHOLE LIFE.
I DON'T KNOW IF I COULD HAVE
PREDICTED IT.
THERE WAS SOMETHING OFF ABOUT
HIM.
I KNEW HIM CLOSELY WHEN WE WERE
VERY YOUNG IN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
TOGETHER.
HE WAS ALWAYS A LITTLE BIT
DIFFERENT.
HE MOSTLY STUCK TO HIMSELF.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU CAN SAY YOU
COULD HAVE PREDICTED THIS.
>> HE WAS BY ALL ACCOUNTS A
PRETTY CLEVER YOUNG MAN, ALMOST
A GENIUS IN MATH.
TELL ME ABOUT THAT SIDE OF HIM.
>> I WAS NEVER IN ANY OF HIS
CLASSES OR ANYTHING LIKE THAT,
BUT YEAH, YOU COULD DEFINITELY
TELL HE WAS I WOULD SAY A
GENIUS.
THERE WAS DEFINITELY SOMETHING
THERE THAT WAS A LITTLE BIT
ABOVE THE REST OF US.
>> DID HE HAVE FRIENDS?
WAS HE SOCIABLE?
>> I ALWAYS SAW HIM ALONE WHEN
HE WAS WALKING THROUGH THE
SCHOOL OR SITTING AT THE TABLE,
SITTING ON THE BUS.
I'M SURE HE HAD A FEW MAYBE
CLOSE FRIENDS THROUGH SCHOOL OR
THROUGH HIS CLASSES.
MOST OF THE TIME I SAW HIM, HE
WAS ALONE.
>> HOW WOULD YOU DESCRIBE HIS
PERSONALITY?
>> HE WAS REALLY QUIET.
HE KEPT TO HIMSELF.
HE WAS A LITTLE FIDGETY.
A LITTLE UNEASY SOMETIMES IF YOU
WERE TO LOOK AT HIM.
I THINK HE WAS JUST SOCIALLY NOT
REALLY INTO GOING OUT THERE AND
MAKING AS MANY FRIENDS AS
EVERYONE WAS DOING IN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AND MIDDLE SCHOOL.
HE PREFERRED TO STAY TO HIMSELF.
>> DID YOU KNOW HIS FAMILY, HIS
MOTHER IN PARTICULAR?
>> I KNEW HER BECAUSE WE LIVED
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
I KNEW HER THROUGH NEIGHBORHOOD
EVENTS.
MY MOM KNEW HER.
SHE WAS A VERY NICE WOMAN.
A KINDERGARTEN TEACHER
OBVIOUSLY.
I DIDN'T KNOW HER PERSONALLY,
BUT FROM WHAT I REMEMBER, SHE
WAS A NICE WOMAN.
>> HIS PARENTS GOT DIVORCED.
WERE YOU AWARE OF THAT HAVING A
BIG IMPACT ON HIM?
>> I DON'T KNOW WHEN THEY GOT
DIVORCED.
I HAVE KNOWN HIM SINCE ABOUT
FIRST GRADE AND HE HAS ALWAYS
BEEN THE WAY I DESCRIBED HIM.
HE'S ALWAYS BEEN RESERVED,
QUIET.
SO I DON'T KNOW IF THE DIVORCE
HAD ANYTHING TO DO WITH THAT OR
WHEN THEY DIVORCED.
THAT COULD HAVE CAUSED THAT OR
MADE IT WORSE AS HE GOT OLDER
AND BECAME A LITTLE BIT MORE
RESERVED.
I'M NOT SURE IF THAT AFFECTED
IT.
>> WHERE WERE YOU WHEN YOU HEARD
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED AND WHAT WAS
YOUR IMMEDIATE REACTION WHEN YOU
DISCOVERED IT WAS THIS PERSON
YOU KNEW?
>> IT WAS DEVASTATING.
I'M IN LONDON NOW STUDYING HERE
FOR THE SEMESTER AND COMING HOME
ON THURSDAY TO THIS.
I FOUND OUT FIRST EARLY THIS
MORNING I GUESS PROBABLY WHEN IT
BROKE AT HOME.
IT WAS AROUND 2:00 AND THE FIRST
INFORMATION OF IT, IT'S
DEFENSE TATE -- DEVASTATING TO
THINK SOMETHING LIKE THAT COULD
HAPPEN IN A TOWN WHERE YOU
LIVED.
I FELT SAFE MY WHOLE LIFE AND I
WAS RAISED IN THAT ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AND THE SCHOOL SYSTEM
THERE AND FINDING OUT IT WAS
SOMEONE I KNEW WHO HAD DONE ALL
OF THIS IS JUST UPSETTING.
YOU CAN'T IMAGINE THAT WOULD
EVER HAPPEN.
>> THE COMMUNITY AROUND NEWTOWN,
HOW WOULD YOU DESCRIBE IT?
I'M HEARING IT WAS A VERY --
IT'S A KIND OF QUIET PLACE AND
THIS STUFF NEVER HAPPENS.
THEY DON'T GET MANY SHOOTINGS
AND GUN MURDERS.
THIS IS AN EXCEPTIONAL KIND OF
PLACE IN THAT SENSE.
>> NO.
I MEAN IT'S A PRETTY BIG TOWN
SPACE-WISE.
WE SPAN OVER A PRETTY VAST ARRAY
OF LAND, BUT IT'S REALLY
CLOSE-KNIT IN THAT EVERYONE
KNOWS EACH OTHER AND IS CLOSE
WITH EACH OTHER AND THE SCHOOL
SYSTEMS ARE CLOSE.
YOU GROW UP WITH THESE PEOPLE
AND GO TO SCHOOL WITH THEM.
EVERYONE CAME TOGETHER I THINK
THROUGH THIS.
THEY ARE REALLY SUPPORTING EACH
OTHER QUITE WELL.
THAT'S ONE GOOD THING TO COME
OUT OF IT IF ANYTHING.
>> WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME YOU
SPOKE TO ADAM LANZA?
>> PROBABLY MIDDLE SCHOOL.
I DIDN'T HAVE ANY CONNECTION
WITH HIM IN HIGH SCHOOL.
MIDDLE SCHOOL PROBABLY.
THE LAST TIME I SAID A WORD TO
HIM.
>> YOUR SUMMARY IS KIND OF
FIDGETY AND SLIGHTLY A LONER AND
NOT MASSIVELY SOCIABLE, BUT NOT
APPARENTLY DANGEROUS.
>> NO, I MEAN I NEVER NOTICED
ANYTHING SCARY OR VIOLENT OR
ANYTHING LIKE THAT.
I WOULD NEVER HAVE EXPECTED THAT
FROM HIM, I DON'T THINK.
JUST FOR SOMEONE WHO SORT OF
WENT UNDER THE RADAR AND KEPT TO
THEMSELVES, YOU WOULDN'T REALLY
THINK OF THEM AS DOING SOMETHING
CRAZY LIKE THIS.
>> IT MUST HAVE BEEN A HECK OF A
SHOCK TO YOU AND I AM GRATEFUL
FOR YOU JOINING US TO GIVE US
PERSPECTIVE ON THE CHARACTER OF
THIS PERSON.
I APPRECIATE YOU JOINING ME.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> COMING UP NEXT, THE
PSYCHOLOGY OF THE SHOOTER, ADAM
LANZA.
TWO EXPERTS ARE HERE TO TALK
ABOUT THE GUNMAN.
>>> EARLIER TODAY, A NUMBER OF
OUR CITIZENS, BEAUTIFUL
CHILDREN, HAD THEIR LIFE TAKEN
AWAY FROM THEM.
AS WELL AS ADULTS WHOSE
RESPONSIBILITY IT WAS TO EDUCATE
AND SUPERVISE THOSE CHILDREN.
THE PERPETRATOR OF THE CRIME IS
DEAD.
AS IS AN INDIVIDUAL WHO THE
PERPETRATOR LIVED WITH.
>> THE CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR
TALKING ABOUT THIS TRAGEDY.
WE HAVE NEW INFORMATION ON THE
GUNMAN, ADAM LANZA.
HE WAS WEARING A BULLET PROOF
VEST.
WHAT COULD HAVE DRIVEN HIM TO DO
WITH THIS?
WELCOME TO YOU BOTH.
LET ME START WITH YOU, DR.
AMADORE.
YOU'VE BEEN INVOLVED IN MANY OF
THESE KINDS OF INCIDENTS AND
POSSIBLY NOTHING AS APPALLING AS
THIS.
THERE SEEMS TO BE A PATTERN WITH
AURORA AND THE SHOPPING MALL
SHOOTING LAST WEEK.
YOUNG MEN IN THEIR EARLY 20s
SUDDENLY FLIPPING AND GETTING
AHOLD OF WEAPONS AND CAUSING
OUTRAGES.
WHAT IS DRIVING THEM?
WHAT IS THE POSSIBLE BACKGROUND
TO WHAT IS GOING ON HERE?
>> WORKING ON A LOT OF THESE
CASES, THERE ARE A NUMBER OF
DIFFERENT CAUSES THAT CAN BE
DIVIDED INTO TWO BROAD
CATEGORIES.
ONE CATEGORY IS PEOPLE WHO HAVE
THAT TRAIT OF A LOSS OF EMPATHY
AND INABILITY TO CONNECT TO
OTHER PEOPLE AND A HISTORY OF
CRUELTY OR WHAT PEOPLE TALK
ABOUT AS SOCIOPATHS OR
ANTISOCIAL PERSONALITY.
AT THE OTHER END PEOPLE WITH
BRAIN DISORDERS AND SERIOUS
MENTAL ILLNESSES THAT ARE
UNTREATED OR BECAUSE OF WHAT'S
HAPPENING IN THEIR LIFE,
EXACERBATED BY STRESS.
IT SOUNDS LIKE THE LITTLE BIT
THAT IS COMING OUT, WE ARE MORE
IN A DIRECTION THAT THIS IS
SOMEONE WITH A BRAIN DISORDER
AND OTHER PARTS OF THE STORY
THAT IT MAY TAKE YEARS TO
UNCOVER WHAT TRIGGERED THIS.
THERE IS NOTHING SUDDEN ABOUT
ANY OF THESE STORIES.
THAT'S THE HEADLINE FOR ME.
IT'S SUDDEN FOR US THAT THIS
HAPPENED.
AS YOU BEGIN TO UNDERSTAND THE
STORY, I ASSURE YOU THE WARNING
SIGNS WERE THERE.
NOT THAT THEY WERE IGNORED, BUT
THEY WERE NOT RECOGNIZED.
>> ARE PEOPLE LIKE THIS AS
LIKELY TO CARRY OUT WHAT THEY
END UP DOING IF THEY DIDN'T HAVE
EASY ACCESS TO FIREARMS?
>> LOOK, THERE IS NO QUESTION
THAT FIREARMS PLAY A ROLE.
I CAN TELL YOU FROM EXPERIENCE
IF SOMEBODY WANTS TO KILL A
NUMBER OF PEOPLE, THERE OTHER
WEAPONS OF DESTRUCTION AND WAYS
TO MAKE BOMBS AND AT LEAST ONE
CASE I WORKED ON.
FIREARMS ARE CERTAINLY AN
IMPORTANT PART OF THE PICTURE,
BUT UNDERSTANDING WHEN SOMEBODY
HAS A MENTAL ILLNESS IF IT
HAS PLAYED A ROLE HERE, AND I'M
NOT SAYING I KNOW THAT IT HAS,
BUT IT NEEDS TO BE
CAREFULLY CONSIDERED BEFORE
ALLOWING THAT PERSON TO HAVE A
FIREARM.
>> FRANK, YOU SPECIALIZE IN
TREATING POST TRAUMATIC STRESS
AND THE EFFECTS OF VIOLENCE.
A VERY PARTICULAR PROBLEM HERE
WITH SO MANY YOUNG PEOPLE AT THE
SCHOOL WHO HAVE LUCKILY
SURVIVED.
HAVING TO DEAL NOW WITH TH
HORROR OF LOSING POSSIBLE
FRIENDS AND PEOPLE THAT THEY
KNEW FROM THE SCHOOL AND
TEACHERS AND THE HEAD TEACHER
AND SO ON.
WHERE DO YOU START WITH TRYING
TO COUNSEL YOUNG CHILDREN WHEN
THIS KIND OF APPALLING THING
HAPPENS?
>> I THINK THE FIRST THING IS
HELPING THE PARENTS.
THE CHILDREN LOOK TO THEIR
PARENTS AND FOR THE PARENTS,
SOME OF THEM ARE STUNNED.
THEY ARE GRIEVING.
THEY LOST A PRECIOUS 6-YEAR-OLD.
FOR THE CHILDREN THEMSELVES,
SOMETIMES CHILDREN WHO GO
THROUGH THIS AND DO SURVIVE TAKE
A WHILE TO MAKE SENSE OUT OF IT.
THEY MAY REGRESS AND MOVE
BACKWARDS A YEAR OR TWO IN TERMS
OF THEIR NORMAL DEVELOPMENT.
SOME OF THEM WILL FIGURE OUT
YEARS LATER WHAT ACTUALLY
HAPPENED.
SOME ARE GOING TO DO RELATIVELY
WELL.
THEY WILL BE SADDER AND WISER IN
A WAY.
THE MOST IMPORTANT THING IS WHAT
I SEE HAPPENING RIGHT NOW.
THAT COMMUNITY IS COMING
TOGETHER.
PEOPLE ARE LOVING EACH OTHER.
THE PRESIDENT HAS COME TO REMIND
US THAT WE ARE A NATION WHO
CARES AND HE CAME AS A FATHER.
I AM A FATHER AND A GRANDFATHER.
I HAVE CALLED MY CHILDREN AND I
WANT TO KNOW HOW THEY ARE DOING
WITH THEIR CHILDREN.
AS WE COME TOGETHER, WE DO THE
BEST THAT WE CAN AT A SAD TIME
LIKE THIS.
>> I SUPPOSE THE BIG QUESTION IS
WHY WOULD THIS SHOOTER DO WHAT
HE DID?
GO TO A CLASSROOM AND MURDER SO
MANY YOUNG CHILDREN OF SUCH A
YOUNG TENDER AGE, POSSIBLY THE
CLASSROOM THAT HIS MOTHER WAS
ALREADY KILLED AT THEIR HOME.
CAN YOU TRY TO PIECE FROM YOUR
EXPERIENCE THE THOUGHT PROCESS
HERE?
WHY HE WOULD THEN HAVING KILLED
HIS MOTHER GO TO THE SCHOOL AND
DO WHAT HE DID?
>> I DON'T HAVE A CRYSTAL BALL
AND I HAVEN'T DIAGNOSED OR
ASSESSED HIM.
AND I'M NOT SAYING THAT
PEOPLE WITH MENTAL ILLNESS ARE
NOT MORE VIOLENT.
LET ME BE CRYSTAL CLEAR ABOUT
THAT.
THAT'S NOT THE CASE.
SIMPLY NOT THE DATA WE HAVE.
IF INDEED MENTAL ILLNESS IS A
PART OF THIS, THERE IS A
PARTICULAR PATH THAT NEEDS TO BE
LOOKED AT.
IS THIS SOMEBODY WHO BECAME
SUICIDALLY DEPRESSED.
AND WITH HIS AUTISM,
HIS ROOMMATE ALEX ISRAEL SAID HE
PREFERRED TO STAY ALONE.
A SYMPTOM OF ASPERGER'S AND
THIS IS ONE REPORT COMING OUT,
WHICH MAY OR MAY NOT BE TRUE, IS
SOMETHING IS MISSING IN THE
BRAIN, THE CAPACITY FOR EMPATHY
AND SOCIAL CONNECTION THAT
LEAVES THE PERSON SUFFERING FROM
THIS CONDITION.
THEY ARE PRONE TO SERIOUS
DEPRESSION AND ANXIETY.
IF THEY ARE SUICIDALLY
DEPRESSED, WE DON'T KNOW ENOUGH.
WHAT I AM TRYING TO DO IN
AGREEING TO COME HERE IS TO ASK
PEOPLE TO DON'T RUSH TO JUDGMENT
ABOUT WHO THIS YOUNG MAN IS.
WE DON'T HAVE ENOUGH
INFORMATION.
IF IT WAS MENTAL ILLNESS THAT
PLAYED A ROLE, IT'S AN
OPPORTUNITY FOR US TO DO BETTER.
>> THERE IS A SCHOOL OF THOUGHT
THAT YOU SHOULDN'T GIVE HIM ANY
ATTENTION AND NAME HIM AND SO ON
BECAUSE IT BRINGS ATTENTION TO
HIM.
MY VIEW IS THAT HE'S DEAD AND
WOMAN BE ABLE TO BASQUE IN THE
GLORY OF WHAT HE DID.
>> YOU'RE MAKING THE ASSUMPTION
THAT HE WANTS TO BASS INCOME THE
GLORY OF WHAT WE DID.
WE DON'T KNOW THAT.
I SPEND MANY HOURS WITH MEN LIKE
THIS WHO KILLED DOZENS OF
PEOPLE.
THEY DON'T NECESSARILY WANT
GLORY.
THEY ARE SERIOUSLY ILL.
OTHERS WHO DO WANT GLORY.
YOU ARE RUSHING TO A PARTICULAR
INTERPRETATION OF THIS.
IT'S WAY TOO SOON TO KNOW.
>> AND PIERS --
>> SORRY.
FRANK, GO AHEAD.
>> I WOULD LIKE TO ENDORSE THAT
ALSO.
I KNOW FOR THE WHOLE COUNTRY, WE
REALLY WANT TO KNOW WHY THIS
HAPPENED.
WHEN YOU ARE A PARENT YOU CAN'T
STOP THINKING ABOUT THESE
QUESTIONS THAT YOU ARE ASKING.
WE HAVE TO BE VERY CAREFUL IN
ANSWERING THEM.
WHEN YOU MENTIONED THAT WE HAD
SEVERAL SIMILAR CASES RECENTLY,
YES, THESE WERE SIMILAR IN THAT
GUNS WERE USED AND THEY WERE
SPREE KILLINGS AND MASS
KILLINGS.
I CAN TELL YOU AS A MEDICAL
DOCTOR AND PSYCHIATRIST WHO
WORKED CLOSELY WITH THE FBI ON
CASES, THERE ARE DRAMATICALLY
DIFFERENT MOTIVES AND
MENTALITIES.
THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO DON'T HAVE
A CONSCIENCE.
THEY TORTURE ANIMALS.
THEY HAVE NO BASIS IN THEIR MIND
FOR EMPATHY OR SYMPATHY.
THEY LEARN HOW TO FAKE IT.
ONE OF THE COLUMBINE KILLERS FIT
THAT PATTERN, BUT THE OTHER WAS
COMPLETELY DIFFERENT.
HE WAS NOT A PSYCHOPATH.
IN THE CASE OF THE AURORA
SHOOTER, THE JURY IS NOT IN YET,
BUT I HAVE A FEELING WE WILL
FIND HE WAS ON THE VERGE OF
MAJOR MENTAL ILLNESS ABOUT
DELUSIONS AND HALLUCINATIONS.
ONE TIME IN MY LIFE I WAS
RESPONSIBLE FOR THE FEDERAL
PROGRAM OF MENTAL HEALTH
SERVICES IN AMERICA.
I HAVE TO ADMIT WE FAILED.
WE FAILED AMERICA IN PROTECTING
THE LIVES OF THE SERIOUSLY
MENTALLY ILL.
MOST OF WHAT THEY DO IS SUFFER
IN SILENCE.
THEIR FAMILIES WANT TO DO BETTER
BY THEM AND AS A COUNTRY WE HAVE
NOT STEPPED UP AND BEEN
SYMPATHETIC AND CARING AND
APPROPRIATE FOR THE SERIOUSLY
MENTALLY ILL.
>> AN EXTREMELY IMPORTANT POINT.
WHAT I WAS GOING TO SAY IS YOU
BOTH HAVE MADE EXTREMELY VALID
POINTS.
MY POINT REALLY IS THAT
YOU HAVE THREE SUCCESSIVE
APPALLING MASS SHOOTINGS
INVOLVING YOUNG MEN IN THEIR 20s
WHERE THE BACKGROUND TO ALL OF
THEM WAS NOT DISSIMILAR.
THEY SEEM TO BE FAIRLY NORMAL
KIND OF SLIGHTLY OFF, BUT
NOTHING WITH ALARM BELLS.
THE POINT OF EXAMINING THEIR
CHARACTER IS THAT THERE MUST BE
A GOOD LIKELIHOOD THAT THERE
ARE OTHERS LIKE HG THEM OUT
THERE WHO MAY BE CONSIDERING
SIMILAR ATROCITIES.
HOW DO PEOPLE WHO KNOW THESE
TYPES OF PEOPLE SPOT ANY WARNING
SIGNS?
>> PIERS --
>> LET ME START WITH THE DOCTOR.
>> I'M SORRY.
I HAVE THREE SMALL CHILDREN.
BEFORE THIS INTERVIEW THEY ASKED
ME WHAT I WAS DOING AND WE
TALKED ABOUT THIS FOR ABOUT AN
HOUR AND A HALF.
MY 9-YEAR-OLD GOT FRIGHTENED, HE
GOES TO ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
I EXPLAINED TO HIM THAT THESE
THINGS ARE EXCEEDINGLY RARE.
LET'S NOT FORGET, THIS IS
EXCEEDINGLY RARE.
JUST BECAUSE SOMETHING HAPPENED
IN THE LAST MONTH DOESN'T
STATISTICALLY MAKE IT A COMMON
OCCURRENCE.
LET'S BE CLEAR AND TELL OUR
CHILDREN THAT.
THE OTHER THING IS THAT
THIS IS AN OPPORTUNITY TO TURN
TRAGEDY INTO AN OPPORTUNITY TO
FIX SOME OF THE THINGS THAT ARE
TERRIBLY BROKEN IN OUR MENTAL
HEALTH CARE SYSTEM.
WE DO KNOW HOW TO IDENTIFY
PEOPLE AT RISK FOR VIOLENCE.
IT'S ALL AT THE LEVEL OF STATE
FUNDING.
SORRY ABOUT GET INTO THE
SPECIFICS, BUT IT'S MENTAL
HEALTH CARE AND SCREENING OF NOT
ONLY YOUNG ADULTS AND CHILDREN
WHO OFFER A GOOD ASSESSMENT, WE
CAN IN FACT DO A MUCH BETTER JOB
OF NOT ONLY CARING FOR THE
PEOPLE AND IDENTIFY THOSE WHO
WOULD NEVER BE VIOLENT IF NOT
FOR A MENTAL ILLNESS.
THAT IS ONE BIT OF THE STORY.
THERE IS ANOTHER PART WHICH IS
WHAT I THINK THAT MOST PEOPLE
ARE MORE FAMILIAR WITH AND
INTERESTED IN BECAUSE OF MOVIES.
THE DIABOLICAL SOCIOPATH.
BOTH STORIES ARE TRUE, BUT BOTH
ARE ACTUALLY QUITE RARE.
>> THE FINAL WORD, MAKE IT BRIEF
IF YOU MAY.
>> AMERICA HAS MORE GUN DEATHS
THAN ANY OTHER ADVANCED NATION
IN THE WORLD.
WE HAVE LAWS THAT SAY IF YOU ARE
SERIOUSLY MENTALLY ILL, YOU
SHOULDN'T POSSESS A WEAPON AND
WE DON'T ENFORCE THE LAWS.
WE HAVE TO GET TOGETHER ACROSS
THIS DIVIDE AND NEED THE NRA TO
STEP UP AND SAY THEY BELIEVE IN
GUN SAFETY AND NOT JUST IN GUN
OWNERSHIP.
WE NEED POLITICIANS ON BOTH
SIDES OF THE AISLE TO TACKLE
THIS PROBLEM.
OR WE'RE GOING TO HAVE MORE DEAD
AMERICAN CHILDREN.
>> THANKOU BOTH VERY MUCH.
STILL AHEAD, WE WILL TALK TO
SURVIVORS OF ANOTHER SHOOTING,
BUT NEXT THE PUSH FOR MORE GUN
CONTROL AFTER THE TRAGEDY.
WE'LL DEBATE IT.
ñ?
>>> THESE NEIGHBORHOODS ARE OUR
NEIGHBORHOODS.
THESE CHILDREN ARE OUR CHILDREN.
WE ARE GOING TO HAVE TO COMING
TO AND TAKE MEANINGFUL ACTION TO
PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS
REGARDLESS OF THE POLITICS.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA ON THE
SHOOTING.
THE MASSACRE IS RAISING NEW
QUESTIONS ABOUT THE ACCESS OF
GUNS IN AMERICA.
JOINING ME NOW IS MY PANEL.
LET'S START WITH YOU.
YOU WERE PRETTY OUTSPOKEN SAYING
THIS IS TIME TO BRING IN NEW GUN
CONTROL LAWS.
>> YES.
IF THIS DOESN'T WAKE US UP, I
DON'T KNOW WHAT WILL.
I WAS HEARTENED THAT THE
PRESIDENT SAID WE HAD TO TAKE
MEANINGFUL ACTION AND THE ONLY
THING HE CAN DO IS LEAD A
CRUSADE FOR REASONABLE GUN
CONTROL LEGISLATION IN CONGRESS.
THESE MASSACRES ARE TAKING PLACE
MORE AND MORE OFTEN.
WE SAW BAY THE WAY TODAY A
SIMILAR INCIDENT IN CHINA WHERE
A MAD MAN ATTACKED AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN CHINA WITH A KNIFE
WITH 22 INJURED CHILDREN.
INJURED, NOT DEAD.
THAT'S THE DIFFERENCE.
IN THE UNITED STATES WE HAVE
9,000 PEOPLE KILLED WITH GUNS
LAST YEAR IN SIMILAR COUNTRIES
LIKE GERMANY, 170 AND CANADA
150.
THERE IS A REASON FOR THAT.
>> WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE TO SEE IN
TERMS OF SPECIFIC GUN CONTROL?
>> THERE A NUMBER OF PIECES OF
LEGISLATION WE HAVE BEEN
PUSHING.
NO REASONABLE GUNOWNER WHO IS A
SPORTSMAN CAN OBJECT TO BANS ON
ASSAULT WEAPONS MADE ONLY TO
KILL AS MANY HUMAN BEINGS AS
POSSIBLE LIKE IN A MILITARY
SITUATION.
NO ONE CAN OBJECT TO A BAN ON
THE SALE OF LARGE AMMUNITION
CLIPS SO YOU CAN'T RELOAD.
NO ONE CAN OBJECT TO
MICROSTAMPING OF CAR TRAJ --
CARTRIDGES SO YOU CAN TRACE THE
MURD E WE POP.
NO ONE CAN OBJECT TO ELIMINATING
THE GUNSHOT EXCEPTION SO EVEN IF
YOU BUY A GUN AT A GUN SHOW,
THEY STILL HAVE TO CHECK YOUR
BACKGROUND TO MAKE SURE THEY ARE
NOT SELLING TO SOMEONE ON A
TERRORIST WATCH LIST OR MENTALLY
UNSTABLE PERSON OR A FELON.
THOSE ARE THE REASONABLE THINGS
WE SHOULD DO.
>> WE HAD A HEATED DEBATE ON A
PREVIOUS INCIDENT.
TWO THINGS HAPPENED IN 1996.
THERE WAS A MASSACRE IN TASMANIA
IN WHICH 35 PEOPLE WERE KILLED.
THE AUSTRALIANS, LED BY THE
PRIME MINISTER, HE BROUGHT IN
DRACONIAN LAWS AFTER THAT.
HE BANNED SEMI AUTOMATIC RIFLES
AND SHOT GUNS.
AS A RESULT OF THE NEXT DECADE,
FIREARM HOMICIDE RATE FELL BY
59% AND SUICIDE RATE FELL BY
65%.
>> NOT TRUE.
>> IT IS TRUE.
>> NO, IT'S NOT.
IF YOU LOOK OVER TIME --
>> IT IS TRUE.
>> I'M TELLING YOU PEOPLE CAN
LOOK UP THE STATISTICS
THEMSELVES.
WHAT YOU FIND IS FOR DECADES THE
MURDER RATE WAS FALLING IN
AUSTRALIA.
IT BASICALLY STOPPED FALLING.
IF YOU JUST COMPARE THE AVERAGE
OVER TWO DECADES WHERE IT'S
FALLING TO WHAT IT WAS
AFTERWARDS, IT MAKES
IT LOOK LIKE THE AVERAGE BEFORE
IS HIGHER THAN AFTERWARDS.
IF YOU LOOK ON A YEAR BY YEAR
BASIS, THERE WASN'T THAT FALL.
>> WHY DOES ADAM LANZA'S MOTHER
NEED TO HAVE THESE THREE
WEAPONS?
>> CAN I FOLLOW-THROUGH ON THE
AUSTRALIAN THING?
>> NO, WHY DOES SHE NEED TO HAVE
THESE THREE WEAPONS, LEGALLY
PURCHASED, INCLUDING THIS SEMI
AUTOMATIC BUSHMASTER?
WHY WOULD A WOMAN TEACHER AT A
KINDERGARTEN NEED THESE WEAPONS
IN HER HOME, ALLOWING A CLEARLY
DERANGED SON TO TAKE THEM AND
COMMIT THIS ATROCITY?
>> WHATEVER THAT GUN LOOKS LIKE,
IT'S A SEMI AUTOMATIC RIFLE.
ANY HUNTING RIFLE IS SEMI
AUTOMATIC.
JUST BECAUSE IT LOOKS DIFFERENT
ON THE OUTSIDE DOESN'T MEAN IT
FUNCTIONS DIFFERENTLY.
HE FIRED OVER 100 ROUNDS IN
SEVERAL MINUTES WITH THIS
APPARENTLY HARMLESS RIFLE.
>> NOBODY SAID GUNS ARE
HARMLESS.
>> YOU ARE TRYING TO SAY IT'S AN
AVERAGE GUN.
HE FIRED OVER 100 ROUNDS AND
KILLED 20 CHILDREN.
20 CHILDREN BETWEEN 5 AND 10.
WHAT POINT DO YOU GUN LOBBY GUYS
SAY WE GET IT?
IT'S TIME FOR CHANGE?
>> IT IS TIME.
>> TIME TO DO WHAT?
>> TO GET RID OF THE GUN LAWS
THAT CAUSE --
>> WHICH ONES?
>> LOOK AT WHAT HAPPENED.
ALL THESE ATTACKS THIS YEAR
OCCURRED WHERE GUNS ARE BANNED.
LOOK AT THE AURORA SHOOTING.
THERE WAS SEVEN MOVIE --
>> WHAT THE HELL HAS THAT GOT TO
DO WITH IT?
SERIOUSLY.
WHAT HAS THAT GOT TO DO WITH IT?
>> YOU NEVER LET ME EXPLAIN.
CAN I SAY SOMETHING?
>> IS IT A GUN-FREE ZONE.
>> LOOK AT THE MOVIE THEATER
ONE.
THERE WERE SEVEN MOVIE THEATERS
SHOWING THE BATMAN MOVIE WITHIN
A 20-MINUTE DRIVE OF WHERE THE
KILLER LIVED.
ONLY ONE OF THOSE BANNED GUNS.
HE DIDN'T GO TO THE THEATER
CLOSEST TO HIS HOME.
HE WENT TO THE ONE THEATER THAT
BANNED GUNS.
IF YOU LOOK AT BANS GENERALLY,
YOU CAN'T POINT TO A PLACE,
CHICAGO, D.C. WHERE WE BAN GUNS
AND MURDER RATES AND VIOLENT
CRIMES WENT UP.
IN THE UK IN JAMAICA AND
IRELAND, ISLAND NATIONS THAT
BANNED GUNS, YOU CAN'T FIND A
PLACE WHERE MURDER RATES HAVE
GONE DOWN.
THEY HAVE GONE UP USUALLY BY
LARGE AMOUNTS.
>> YOU CANNOT FIND A PLACE --
>> FIRST OF ALL, BASICALLY EVERY
STATISTIC THAT JOHN CITED IS
PURE BUNK IN TERMS OF THE FACT
THAT THE MORE GUNS EQUAL --
THAT'S TRUE.
THEY WERE GUN-FREE ZONES, BUT
ATTRIBUTING THAT TO THE FACT
THAT THIS VIOLENCE OCCURRED,
THAT'S WHERE I HAVE TO STEP IN.
LISTEN, MY BROTHER WAS SHOT IN A
SHOOTING ON TOP OF THE EMPIRE
STATE BUILDING WHICH WAS
CHAOTIC.
I KNOW FIRSTHAND I TALKED WITH
THE VICTIMS FROM THE AURORA
TRAGEDY.
AND ALL THESE TRAGEDIES.
TO A PERSON, THEY ALL SAY IF
THERE WERE ANOTHER PERSON ARMED,
IT WOULD HAVE LED TO MORE
CARNAGE.
>> THEY'VE STOPPED MANY CASES.
>> EXCUSE ME.
>> NAME ONE CASE WHERE THAT'S
HAPPENED.
IF EVERY ONE OF THE CASES THEY
SAY IF THERE WERE MORE GUNS, IT
WOULD HAVE ONLY LED TO MORE
CHAOS.
LOOK AT THE EMPIRE BUILDING
SHOOTING HERE IN NEW YORK.
THERE WERE HIGHLY TRAINED
OFFICERS IN THE CHAOS AND EIGHT
OTHER PEOPLE SHOT AND EVERY ONE
WAS AN INNOCENT CIVILIAN AND
EVERY ONE WAS SHOT BY A LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICER.
>> WE HAVE THE ATTORNEY FOR THE
RESPONSIBLE GUN OWNERS.
YOU BELIEVE THAT THERE SHOULD BE
MORE GUNS IN SCHOOLS.
IS THAT RIGHT?
>> I BELIEVE THOSE OF US WHO ARE
LICENSED TO CARRY ARE
RESPONSIBLE PEOPLE AND SHOULDN'T
BE PROHIBITED FROM CARRYING IN
SCHOOLS OR OTHER PLACES.
IN FACT, THE MICHIGAN
LEGISLATURE PASSED A BILL LAST
NIGHT AND SENT TO THE GOVERNOR
FOR SIGNATURE A BILL THAT WOULD
ALLOW THOSE OF US WHO ARE
LICENSED TO TAKE MORE DAY OF
TRAINING INCLUDING RANGE TIME
AND BE ABLE TO CARRY IN THE
PLACES WHERE WE COULDN'T CARRY
BEFORE.
>> WHY ON EARTH WOULD YOU WANT
MORE GUNS IN SCHOOLS AFTER WHAT
HAPPENED TODAY?
>> HERE'S WHY, PIERS.
IF WE COULD SUDDENLY MAKE ALL
GUNS DISAPPEAR, I WOULD HAVE A
DIFFERENT POSITION.
I SPEND A LOT OF TIME THINKING
ABOUT THIS AND READING ABOUT
THIS.
I TEACH A CLASS CALLED GUN
CONTROL SEMINAR AND I GET A NEW
GROUP OF LAW STUDENTS EVERY TERM
AND WE DISCUSS THIS IN DETAIL.
THE SIMPLE FACTS ARE GUNS EXIST.
THEY ARE ESSENTIALLY 1800s
TECHNOLOGY.
EVEN SELL U AUTOMATICS CAME INTO
BEING IN THE LATE 1800s.
THEY ARE EASY TO MAKE AND LAST
SEVERAL HUMAN LIFETIMES WITH
MINIMAL MAINTENANCE.
SINCE GUNS EXIST AND WE KNOW FOR
A FACT THAT THE ONLY WAY TO
STOP AN EVIL PERSON LIKE THE
PERSON YOU WERE DISCUSSING
EARLIER IN THE SHOW IS TO SHOOT
THEM.
>> HANG ON.
THIS IS EXACTLY THE ARGUMENT I
HAVE BEEN HEARING EVER SINCE I
JOINED CNN.
I JOINED ON AIR ABOUT A WEEK
AFTER GABBY GIFFORDS THE
CONGRESSWOMAN WAS SHOT IN THE
HEAD.
EVER SINCE THEN, WE HAVE THE
SIKH TEMPLE AND AURORA AND THE
SHOPPING MALL AND SO ON AND SO
ON.
GUY DOWNSTAIRS SHOT IN FRONT OF
OUR NEW YORK BUREAU.
THE ARGUMENT I KEEP HEARING IF
EVERYBODY WAS WAS ARMED, IT
WOULDN'T HAPPEN.
IT'S HOG WASH, ISN'T IT?
IF EVERYONE IN THAT MOVIE
THEATER HAD GUNS, MORE PEOPLE
WOULD HAVE BEEN KILLED IN THE
MAYHEM THAT ERUPTED.
>> GIVE AN EXAMPLE --
>> THERE IS PROOF --
>> THEY HAVE REASONABLE LAWS AND
THEY HAVE 100 PEOPLE A YEAR NOT
9,000 OR 10,000 A YEAR.
>> LISTEN --
>> IT WAS LOWER BEFORE GUN
CONTROL.
>> THEY GOT THE GUN CONTROL
LAWS --
>> THE POINT IS GUN CONTROL
DIDN'T CHANGE IT.
>> SCOTLAND IN 1996 THERE WAS A
SIMILAR SCHOOL SHOOTING.
JUST AN AWFUL SITUATION.
16 YOUNG CHILDREN KILLED EXACTLY
AS THEY WERE TODAY.
AS A RESULT OF THIS, THEY
BROUGHT IN A HANDGUN BAN.
162,000 HANDGUNS WERE HANDED IN.
IT IS TIME FOR THIS.
>> MURDER RATES WENT UP.
>> THERE ABOUT 35 MURDERS A
YEAR.
>> BUT IT WAS LOWER FOR ANOTHER
REASONING.
>> THERE ARE 12,000 MURDERS A
YEAR FROM GUNS IN THIS COUNTRY.
WHEN ARE YOU GUYS GOING TO FOCUS
ON THAT AND STOP TELLING ME THE
ANSWER IS MORE GUNS.
IT IS NOT THE ANSWER.
>> LISTEN, LISTEN, LISTEN --
>> AFTER THE BAN, IT WAS HIGHER
THAN IT WAS BEFORE THE BAN.
>> YOU WANT MORE GUNS AND NOT
LESS?
300 MILLION GUNS IN AMERICA IS
NOT ENOUGH FOR YOU?
>> WHEN YOU BAN GUNS --
>> HOW MANY MORE KIDS HAVE TO
DIE BEFORE YOU GUYS SAY WE WANT
LESS GUNS, NOT MORE?
>> HE ASKED ME A QUESTION.
>> LET HIM ANSWER THE QUESTION.
>> I'M UPSET BECAUSE I WORRY
THAT THE GUN CONTROL LAWS THAT
YOU'RE PUSHING HAVE KILLED
PEOPLE.
>> OH, WHAT A LOAD OF NONSENSE.
NONSENSE.
AVERAGE OF 35 KILLINGS IN
BRITAIN A YEAR IN A PLACE OF
BANNED HANDGUNS.
>> BUT IT WAS MORE BEFORE THEY
HAD THE GUN CONTROL LAWS.
>> I HAVE BEEN DEBATING THIS ALL
WEEK WITH THE SHOPPING MALL
SHOOTING AND MONTHS IF NOT TWO
YEARS.
I AM SO FRUSTRATED AND FURIOUS
FOR THESE KIDS WHO ARE BEING
BLOWN AWAY AGAIN WITH LEGALLY
ACQUIRED WEAPONS.
SOME BOY WHO HAS PROBLEMS TAKES
HIS MOTHER'S THREE WEAPONS
INCLUDING THIS RIDICULOUS
ASSAULT RIFLE AND GOES IN THE
SCHOOL AND KILLS THESE KIDS AND
YOU GUYS STILL WANT TO TELL ME
THE ANSWER IS MORE GUNS?
IT IS MADNESS!
>> HOW ELSE CAN YOU STOP SOMEONE
FROM SHOOTING PEOPLE.
WHAT ARE WE MOST ANGRY ABOUT?
EVERY POLL SHOWS BY MASSIVE
MAJORITIES AMERICANS AGREE WITH
WHAT YOU SAID.
YET WE HAVE A LOBBY.
THE LEADERSHIP OF THE NRA, WHO
FUNCTION AS ENABLELERS OF MASS
MURDERERS.
>> ABSOLUTELY NOT TRUE.
>> THEY TERRIFY THE POLITICAL
PEOPLE AND EVEN THOUGH
POLLING SHOWS THAT MOST NRA
MEMBERS WOULD SUPPORT REASONABLE
GUN CONTROLS, THEY COME IN AND
LIE AND SAY THEY WILL TAKE YOUR
GUNS AWAY AND STOP ANY
LEGISLATION TO PREVENT THAT.
>> NOBODY OUTSIDE THE MILITARY
AND POLICE IN THIS COUNTRY NEEDS
ONE OF THESE.
NOBODY, END OF STORY.
>> I HAVE TO SAY SOMETHING.
>> THE ENCOURAGING THING AND
WHAT YOU SHOULD TAKE INSPIRATION
BECAUSE WE ARE ALL FRUSTRATED
AND OUTRAGED.
THIS CONVERSATION AND WHAT THESE
GUYS ARE SAYING DOES NOT
REPRESENT WHAT THE AMERICAN
PUBLIC WANTS AND THE
CONVERSATION THAT THE AMERICAN
PUBLIC WANTS TO HAVE.
WE ARE ALL IN FAVOR OF THINGS
LIKE CRIMINAL BACKGROUND CHECKS.
74% OF NRA MEMBERS ARE AND MOST
GUN SALES DO NOT REQUIRE A
BACKGROUND CHECK.
THAT'S SOMETHING WE ALL AGREE
ON.
THERE ARE THINGS THAT WE CAN
DO --
>> IT'S NOT AS THEY TRY TO TELL
ME AN ANTI-AMERICAN THING TO SAY
I RESPECT THE SECOND AMENDMENT
AND I RESPECT THE RIGHT OF EVERY
FAMILY TO DEFEND THEMSELVES.
I DON'T RESPECT THE RIGHT FOR
FAMILIES TO LOAD THEIR HOMES
WITH THESE SO A DISTURBED KID
CAN TAKE THEM AND SOMETHING INTO
A SCHOOL.
WE ARE ENDING THE DEBATE FOR
NOW, BUT THIS WILL CONTINUE NEXT
WEEK.
COME BACK NEXT WEEK WHEN YOU'VE
HAD TIME TO THINK ABOUT THIS.
YOU HAVE TO CHANGE YOUR
THINKING.
THE GUN LOBBY HAS TO CHANGE ITS
>> WHY DO ALL OF THESE --
>> WE'LL LEAVE IT THERE.
COMING NEXT, SURVIVORS FROM
OTHER MASS SHOOTINGS SHARE THEIR
THOUGHTS ON TODAY'S APPALLING
MASSACRE.
>>> ONE OF THE MOST DISTURBING
IMAGES FROM THE SHOOTING, POLICE
OFFICERS ESCORTING
SCHOOLCHILDREN FROM THE SCHOOL.
ANOTHER PICTURE FROM THE MASS
SHOOTING IN 1999.
FROM A JEWISH CENTER IN
CALIFORNIA.
WE HAVE A VICTIM OF THE
SHOOTING, JOINS ME NOW.
AND WE HAVE ANOTHER JCC
SURVIVOR, AND A SURVIVOR OF THE
TRAGEDY IN AURORA, AND THE
BROTHER OF A SHOOTING AT THE
EMPIRE STATE BUILDING.
WELCOME TO YOU ALL.
LET ME START IF I MAY WITH JOSH.
THIS MUST HAVE BROUGHT BACK
AWFUL MEMORIES FOR YOU TODAY, AS
IT DOES I WOULD IMAGINE WHENEVER
THERE IS A MASS SHOOTING IN
AMERICA.
WHAT WERE YOUR FEELINGS?
>> IT'S -- IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO
PUT WORDS TO WHAT I REALLY FEEL.
IT'S A MIXTURE OF SYMPATHY AND
DISGUST.
AND MY HEART GOES OUT TO THOSE
FAMILIES AND THERE ARE PEOPLE
WHO HAVE GONE THROUGH THE SAME
THING AND WHO UNDERSTAND WHAT
ARE YOU GOING THROUGH, AND
IMMEDIATELY WHAT I THOUGHT WAS
JUST THAT I WISH THAT THERE WAS
SOMETHING I COULD DO TO HELP
THEM.
BUT, YOU KNOW, IN REALITY, IT'S
A HELPLESS SITUATION.
>> MINDY, YOU SURVIVED WHAT
HAPPENED TO YOU.
WHEN YOU HEAR THE RAGING GUN
DEBATE, WHICH WILL BE
PARTICULARLY VOCIFEROUS IN LIGHT
OF THIS APPALLING ACT TODAY.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
DO YOU WISH WHAT HAPPENED AFTER
YOU AND JOSH TOUGHER LAWS HAD
BEEN BROUGHT IN AFTER THAT TO
TRY AND DO SOMETHING ABOUT THIS?
>> YOU KNOW, I DO.
I THINK JOSH AND I AND EVERYONE
IN OUR COMMUNITY IN THIS WEIRD
FAMILY WE HAVE, SURVIVORS OF GUN
VIOLENCE, WISHES THE DAY AFTER
WHAT HAPPENED TO THEM, NOBODY
ELSE HAS TO GO THROUGH IT.
UNFORTUNATELY, 13.5 YEARS LATER,
WE'RE SITTING HERE WATCHING
THESE TRAGEDIES UNFOLD ON A
DAILY BASIS.
>> YOU WERE 16 AT THE TIME OF
THE SHOOTING.
OBVIOUSLY, A LOT OF KIDS AT THE
SCHOOL TODAY WILL BE MUCH
YOUNGER THAN THAT, AND THEY WILL
HAVE EITHER LOST FRIENDS OR
PEOPLE THEY KNEW AT THE SCHOOL
IT WILL BE VERY DIFFICULT FOR
THEM WHEN THEY HAVE TO GO BACK.
WHAT ADVICE WOULD YOU GIVE THEM?
WHAT IS THE BEST WAY TO TRY AND
DEAL WITH THIS?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
>> YOU KNOW, TO BE HONEST, IT'S
HEARTBREAKING.
BECAUSE THEY ARE NOT GOING TO
KNOW REALLY WHAT OR HOW TO FEEL
UNTIL FIVE, TEN YEARS FROM NOW,
WHEN IT ACTUALLY KEEPS HAUNTING
THEM AND NIGHTMARES AND FEARS
THAT KEEP COMING UP.
JOSH CAN SPEAK TO THAT HIMSELF,
HE WAS SIX YEARS OLD AT THE
TIME, AND, YOU KNOW, NOW HE'S IN
HIS 20s AND IT HAUNTS HIM EVERY
DAY.
I WAS 16, I KNEW WHY I WAS SHOT.
I KNEW SOMEBODY TRIED TO KILL
ME, AND EVERY DAY, MY ENTIRE
LIFE, I'M ALMOST 30 YEARS OLD,
I'M HAUNTED.
THERE IS NOTHING I CAN SAY TO
THEM THAT I AM SO, SO SORRY THEY
HAVE TO GO THROUGH THIS, AND I
REALLY TRULY HOPE SOMETHING WILL
BE DONE AFTER TODAY, BECAUSE WE
CANNOT STAND FOR THIS ANYMORE.
>> STEVEN BARTON, YOU SURVIVED
THE AURORA MASSACRE A FEW MONTHS
AGO, A HUGE OUTCRY THEN AND
PEOPLE PROMISED TO DO ALL SORTS
OF THINGS, POLITICIAN MOUTHS THE
USUAL RHETORIC, ABSOLUTELY
NOTHING HAPPENED, AND LO AND
BEHOLD, HERE WE ARE WITH AN EVEN
WORSE TRAGEDY.
MORE DEAD, AND THIS TIME, 20
YOUNG KIDS.
WHAT ARE YOUR VIEWS ABOUT THE
DEBATE THAT WILL NOW UNFOLD ON
THIS?
>> I MEAN, I THINK THE PRESIDENT
SAID WE NEED A MEANINGFUL ACTION
NOW, AND HE SAID THAT IN THE
PAST, AND SO I'LL BE WAITING FOR
THAT ACTION.
IT'S A SHAME THAT 20 CHILDREN
HAVE TO BE SLAIN FOR US TO EVEN
START TALKING ABOUT THIS.
BUT I REALLY THINK THAT THE
AMERICAN PUBLIC IS FED UP WITH
THE LACK OF CONVERSATION ON THIS
ISSUE.
>> AND THERE WILL BE MORE MASS
SHOOTINGS IN THE LAST FIVE OR
SIX YEARS AND IN THE PREVIOUS
FOUR DECADES IN TERMS OF THE
PARTICULARLY APPALLING ONES.
AND YET YOU KEEP BEING TOLD,
WELL, NOT AS BAD AS IT SEEMS.
THE SITUATION, BUT IT TRULY IS.
SINCE I'VE BEEN HERE, I'VE BEEN
UTTERLY HORRIFIED, WHY I GET SO
ANIMATED WHEN I DEBATE IT ON THE
SHOW.
I COME FROM A COUNTRY WHERE THIS
WOULD BE UNTHINKABLE.
MOVIE THEATERS, SHOPPING MALLS,
KINDERGARTEN CLASSROOMS WOULD BE
SHOT DOWN IN AN INDISCRIMINATE
WAY ON A BIMONTHLY BASIS.
I DON'T GET WHY AMERICANS AREN'T
FAR MORE ANGRY.
>> IT'S ONE THING FOR A
POLITICIAN TO TAKE ACTION, BUT
IT'S EQUALLY IMPORTANT THAT THE
AMERICAN PUBLIC DEMANDS THESE
REFORMS, THESE CHANGES, AND THE
POLLING IS CLEAR.
SUPPORT FOR COMMON SENSE GUN
REFORM.
82% OF GUN OWNERS SUPPORT
UNIVERSAL BACKGROUND CHECKS.
IT'S A FAILURE OF THE SYSTEM WE
HAVEN'T ARRIVED AT THAT POINT
YET.
>> PAULA, YOUR BROTHER WAS
KILLED IN THE EMPIRE STATE
BUILDING SHOOTING.
WHEN WE TALKED BEFORE,
YOU BELIEVE IN THE RIGHT TO OWN
A HANDGUN AND A REFERENDUM
ON GUNS WASN'T NEEDED.
WHAT DO YOU FEEL TODAY?
>> I THINK IN THE WAKE OF TODAY
A REFERENDUM ON GUNS IS NEEDED.
I WAS TALKING ON THE DAY MY
BROTHER WAS MURDERED.
AND THIS -- AS A FATHER,
INNOCENT CHILDREN, I SEE THE
HEARTBREAK.
WE HAVE TO GO BACK TO THAT.
WE HAVE 20 FAMILIES, 26 FAMILIES
THAT ARE DEVASTATED RIGHT NOW,