BY TOMORROW MORNING, WE WILL
HAVE AN IDEA AS TO HOPEFULLY
SOME OF THE SCHOOL QUESTIONS
HERE IN THE COMMUNITY.
WE WILL BE IN CONTACT WITH THE
SUPERINTENDENT AND HOPEFULLY
SOME ADDITIONAL INVESTIGATORY
INFORMATION.
THANK YOU, GOOD AFTERNOON.
>> COULD YOU TRACE THAT PHONE
CALL?
>> WE ARE WORKING ON THAT.
>> YOU ARE LISTENING TO PAUL
VANCE OF THE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE.
I'M ERIN BURNETT WITH WOLF
BLITZER.
>> COMING TO YOU FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THE PAIN IS REALLY, REALLY GREAT
ARE THE COUNTRY, NOT ONLY THIS
UP TO BUT THE COUNTRY, INDEED
MUCH OF THE WORLD, MOURNS WHAT
HAS HAPPENED IN THIS COMMUNITY.
>> WE WERE JUST HEARING, WOLF,
LIEUTENANT VANCE SAY THIS WILL
PROBABLY BE THE LAST TIME WE
HEAR FROM HIM TONIGHT BUT SOME
OF THE LATEST THINGS THAT HE
SAID, WOLF THAT THEY STILL DON'T
KNOW THE MOTIVE.
THEY SAY THAT IS GOING TO COME
LATER.
IT IS GOING TO TAKE THEM MORE
TIME BEFORE THEY ARE ABLE TO
TALK ABOUT THAT AND IT IS
IMPOSSIBLE TO SAY HOW MANY SHOTS
WERE FIRED, WOLF, BUT MULTIPLE
HIGH-CAP PAYS THE ROUNDS, EACH
MAGAZINE HAD ABOUT 30 SHOTS AND
SAID HUNDREDS OF BULLETS AT
LEAST.
>> THIS CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
LIEUTENANT IS DOING AN EXCELLENT
JOB BRIEFING US.
HE IS BEING VERY PRECISE ON ALL
OF THE DETAILS, HE DOESN'T WANT
TO GET AHEAD OF THE INFORMATION
THAT THEY HAVE AND SO FAR, I
HAVE BEEN VERY IMPRESSED.
>> YES, MA'AM TO THAT POINT,
THEY ASKED ABOUT NANCY LANZA, HE
SAYS I DON'T KNOW WHICH GUN SHE
WAS SHOT WITH BUT DOES KNOW IT
WAS THE BUSHMASTER THE ONE USED
IN THE SCHOOL, VERY SPECIFIC AND
VERY CAREFUL SO WE KNOW WHAT WE
ARE GETTING IS RIGHT.
WE ARE LEARNING SOME NEW DETAILS
ABOUT HOW THE VICTIMS DIED AND
THE ONGOING INVESTIGATION THIS
AFTERNOON.
HERE IS WHAT WE KNOW RIGHT NOW.
WOLF, POLICE SAY CRIME SCENE
INVESTIGATORS WRAPPING UP WORK
IN THE PARKING LOT OF THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WORK CONTINUES INSIDE THE SCHOOL
AND AS YOU JUST HEARD LIEUTENANT
VANCE TALKING ABOUT, THERE WERE
THREE GUNS FOUND NEXT TO THE
BODY OF THE SUSPECTED GUNSMAN,
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA, HE
KILLED HIMSELF WITH THE HANDGUN
AND USED THE BUSHMASTER AR 15 TO
SHOOT HIS VICTIMS.
THE SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE REALLY
WAS THE MAIN WEAPON USED.
WE HAVE ALSO USED THAT THE 20
CHILDREN KILLED INSIDE THE
SCHOOL WERE SHOT MULTIPLE TIMES,
EVERY SINGLE ONE OF THEM, WOLF,
WAS, OF COURSE, 6 OR 7 YEARS
OLD.
>> SO HEARTBREAKING TO HEAR THE
DETAILS COME OUT AND TO LEARN
ABOUT THESE YOUNG KIDS.
20 OF THEM.
6 AND 7 YEARS OLD.
ALL FIRST GRADERS.
SIX ADULTS AS WELL.
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS ON HIS WAY TO
NEWTOWN RIGHT NOW.
HE HAS TOUCHED DOWN IN
CONNECTICUT A FEW MINUTES AGO.
HE IS NOT GOING TO BE ABLE TO
CHOPPER HERE, HE WILL HAVE TO
DRIVE BECAUSE OF THE INCLEMENT
WEATHER.
HE WILL MEET WITH FAMILIES AND
FIRST RESPONDERS THEN LATER
TONIGHT, HE WILL SPEAK AT AN
INTERFAITH VIGIL HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
WE ARE GOING TO HAVE LIVE
COVERAGE OF THE SERVICE IN ITS
ENTIRETY.
THAT WILL BEGIN AT 7 P.M.
EASTERN.
>>> TODAY, THE FAMILIES OF THE
VICTIMS ARE GRIEVING OR STARTING
TO TRY TO UNDERSTAND THE HORROR
OF WHAT HAS HAPPENED.
DURING THE TIME OF SORROW, SOME
ARE STARTING TO REMEMBER, PEOPLE
ARE OF AN AGE, RIGHT YOU 6 AND
7, WHAT YOU DO IS BRING JOY TO
THE PEOPLE AROUND YOU'S LIVES.
NICK VALENCIA IS IN OUR
NEWSROOM, SOME ARE STARTING TO
PUT PICTURES OF THEIR CHILDREN
ONLINE?
>> YES, THEY ARE, ERIN, GOOD
AFTERNOON TO YOU, AND WOLF.
ERIN, SOME OF THE FAMILIES SO
FAR, AS YOU CAN IMAGINE HAVE
BEEN VERY PRIVATE ABOUT THEIR
LOSS BUT THEY STILL WANT US TO
KNOW ABOUT THEIR LOVED ONES SO
SOME ARE ISSUING STATEMENTS TO
US AND SLOWLY STARTING TO PUT
PICTURES OF THOSE KIDS.
ONE OF THOSE FAMILIES IS A
FAMILY OF YOUNG OLIVIA ENGEL, 6
YEARS OLD, AS YOU CAN IMAGINE,
ERIN, DEVASTATING TIME FOR THEM
A FEW WEEKS AGO, THEY TOOK THESE
PHOTOS FOR CHRISTMAS, FOR THEIR
HOLIDAY SEASON CARDS, SHE LOVED
SCHOOL MORE THAN ANYTHING.
SHE LOVED READING AND MATH AND
SHE WAS ESPECIALLY ACTIVE
OUTSIDE OF THE CLASSROOM AS
WELL.
SHE PLAYED TENNIS.
SHE WENT SWIMMING YOU.
SHE WAS IN BALLET AND THE DAISY
GIRL SCOUTS.
IN A STATEMENT TO CNN, THE ENGEL
FAMILY SAID, "OLIVIA'S LOSS,
PHYSICAL LOSS, WILL BE FELT
EVERY DAY BY THOSE WHO LOVE HERD
MOST BUT HER SPARKLY SPIRIT WILL
LIVE ON."
ACCORDING TO HER FATHER, BRIAN,
HER FAVORITE COMERS WERE PINK
AND PURPLE AND EVERY NIGHT,
ERIN, EVERY NIGHT, SHE SAT AT
THE DINNER TABLE AND LED GRACE
FOR THE FAMILY.
SHE WAS JUST 6 YEARS OLD, JUST A
DEVASTATING TIME FOR THE ENGLE
FAMILY.
ONE OTHER FAMILY THAT WE HAVE
HEARD FROM IS THE FAMILY OF
JESSICA REKOS.
JESSICA 6 YEARS OLD, THE FAMILY,
AS YOU CAN IMAGINE, DID NOT WANT
TO TALK AT LENGTH ABOUT
JESSICA'S LOSS BUT DID WANT HER
TO BE REMEMBERED.
THEY ALSO ISSUED STATEMENT TO
CNN.
I WANT TO READ THAT TO YOU, THEY
SAID "JESSICA LOVED EVERYTHING
ABOUT HORSES.
SHE DEVOTED HER FREE TIME TO
WATCHING HORSE MOVIES, READING
HORSE BOOKS, DRAWING HORSES AND
WRITING STORIES ABOUT HORSES.
WE HAD PROMISED HER SHE COULD
HAVE HER VERY OWN HORSE WHEN SHE
TURNED 10.
THIS YEAR, SHE ASKED SANTA FOR A
NEW COWGIRL BOOTS AND A COWGIRL
HAT.
SHEAFS CREATIVE, BEAUTIFUL
LITTLE GIRL WHO LOVED PLAYING
HER LITTLE BROTHERS, TRAVIS AND
SHANE."
RIGHT NOW, THE REKOS FAMILY IS
STRUGGLING TO EXPLAIN TO THEIR
LITTLE BROTHER, TRAV VICIOUS WHY
HE CAN'T PLAY WITH HIS BEST
FRIEND ANYMORE.
EARLIER THIS YEAR, 6-YEAR-OLD
JESSICA, ONE OF HER DREAMS CAME
TRUE, ERIN, SHE LOVED HORSES BUT
SHE WAS ALSO A BIG FAN OF WHALES
AND HER FAMILY TOOK HER TO
SEAWORLD.
SHE GOT TO SEE AN ORCA WHALE IN
REAL LIFE.
BUT SHE -- THOSE TWO VICTIMS,
JESSICA REKOS AND OLIVIA ENGEL,
TWO OF THE 6-YEAR-OLDS TAKEN TOO
SOON FROM US IN THE NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, SHOOTING AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS.
WHEN THE FAMILIES REACH OUT US
TO, WE WILL GET IN TOUCH WITH
YOU, ERIN AND WOLF.
>> NICK, THANKS VERY MUCH T IS
INTERESTING, SOME OF THESE
PARENTS, THEY WANT TO TALK RIGHT
NOW ABOUT THEIR 6-YEAR-OLD OR
THEIR 7-YEAR-OLD, AT THE TIME
WORLD HOW MUCH THEY LOVED THEM.
OTHERS WANT PRIVACY, WE RESPECT,
OF COURSE, THAT COMPLETELY BUT
THEY WANT US TO SEE AND LEARN
ABOUT THEM.
AND VERY HELPFUL N THESE KINDS
OF TRAGEDIES, I HAVE DISCOVERED
OVER THE YEARS, PEOPLE REACT IN
DIFFERENT WAYS.
WHAT'S GOOD FOR ONE PARENT IS
NOT NECESSARILY GOOD FOR
ANOTHER.
>> PEOPLE DO GRIEVE SO
DIFFERENTLY.
>> YEAH.
THERE'S BEEN SOME POLICE
ACTIVITY IN THE ALLEGED GUNMAN'S
NEIGHBORHOOD.
RIGHT NOW, ALLISON DOES SIC
JOINING US WITH THE LATEST
INFORMATION.
ALLISON WHAT ARE YOU LEARNING?
>> Reporter: WHAT IS
INTERESTING, WE HAVE BEEN TRYING
TO CONFIRM WHETHER OR NOT THE
NEIGHBORHOOD HERE ARE WHERE ADAM
LANZA LIVED WITH HIS MOTHER,
NANCY, WHERE THE SCENE HAS BEEN
CLEARED FROM THE INVESTIGATION.
WE HAVEN'T YET GOTTEN
CONFIRMATION ON THAT, WHAT
HAPPENED I WOULD SAY 20 MINUTES
AGO, ABOUT SIX POLICE CARS DROVE
UP HERE, ABOUT SIX OFFICERS GOT
OUT, TALKED IN THE MIDDLE OF THE
STREET BEHIND MERCK GOT BACK
INTO THEIR CARS AND DROVE INTO
THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
NOT SURE EXACTLY WHERE THEY WERE
HEADED.
WE CAN ONLY ASSUME THEY ARE
HEADED TO THE LANZA HOME OR IN
THAT AREA.
WE ARE LEARNING NEW INFORMATION
TODAY ABOUT HOW THE GUNMAN GOT
INTO SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
AND IT'S INTERESTING TO HEAR
THESE DETAILS.
YOU HAVE TO REMEMBER THE SCHOOL
HAD SECURITY IN THAT YOU HAD TO
BE BUZZED IN BY -- AROUND 9:30,
THE DOORS WOULD BE LOCKED AND
YOU HAD TO BE BUZZED IN AND THE
PEOPLE INSIDE THE SCHOOL COULD
SEE ON A SECURITY CAMERA WHO
WOULD BE TRYING TO GET INTO THE
DOOR.
WE ARE LEARNING FROM CONNECTICUT
GOVERNOR DAN MALLOY THAT WHAT
THIS GUNMAN DID, AND HE IS
ACTUALLY CONFIRMING WHAT OUR
SOURCES HAVE TOLD US BEFORE WHAT
THIS GUNMAN DID WAS BASICALLY
BLAST HIS WAY INTO THE SCHOOL,
BASICALLY SHOOT AN ENTRANCE, HIS
OWN ENTRANCE INTO THE BUILDING.
HERE'S MORE OF WHAT THE GOVERNOR
HAD TO SAY.
>> WHAT WE KNOW IS HE SHOT HIS
WAY INTO THE BUILDING, HE
PENETRATED -- WASN'T BUZZED IN,
PENETRATED BY LITERALLY SHOOTING
AN ENTRANCE INTO THE BUILDING.
THAT'S WHAT AN ASSAULT WEAPON
CAN DO FOR YOU.
WE ARE, UNFORTUNATELY, A VIOLENT
SOCIETY.
>> Reporter: AS WE LEARNED IN
THE NEWS CONFERENCE JUST A SHORT
TIME AGO MORE ABOUT THE WEAPONS
THAT THE GUNMAN MOSTLY USED OR
ONLY USED A BUSHMASTER TO MOW
DOWN THESE KIDS TO JUST MASSACRE
THESE KIDS AND SIX ADULTS INSIDE
THIS SCHOOL, THAT HE USED THAT
AUTOMATIC WEAPON TO DO SO INSIDE
THE SCHOOL AND THEN TURNED THE
HAPPENED GUN ON HIMSELF.
AT THE SAME TIME, WE ARE
LEARNING MORE ABOUT WHAT
AUTHORITIES DOING TO TRACK THESE
WEAPONS.
THE ATF HAS ALREADY TRACED THE
NOW, WHAT FEDERAL AGENTS ARE
DOING RIGHT NOW, THEY ARE
CHASING NEW LEADS, THEY ARE
LOOKING AT 30 GUN RANGES.
THEY ARE LOOKING AT 400 GUN
DEALERS IN A FOUR-COUNTY AREA
SURROUNDING NEWTOWN AND WHAT
THEY ARE TRYING TO DO WOLF, THEY
ARE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHAT
THIS GUNMAN WAS UP TO IN THE
DAYS LEADING UP TO THIS
MASSACRE.
WOLF?
>> ALISON KOSIK WITH THE LATEST
ON THIS PART OF THE STORY.
SOME QUESTIONS THAT HAVE TO BE
ANSWERED.
GET A FEW OF.
THEY I SUSPECT THE NEXT 24, 48
HOURS, WE WILL GET MORE.
>> THE BIG QUESTION IS WHY AND
WE DON'T NOTE ANTICIPATE TO THAT
YES.
ACROSS THE COUNTRY THOUGH,
CHILDREN MAY BE HAVING A HARD
TIME GETTING READY TO GO BACK TO
SCHOOL.
A LOT OF PARENTS WHO ARE
WATCHING MAYBE KEPT THEIR KIDS
AWAY FROM THE TELEVISION ALL
WEEKEND AND ARE DECIDING NOW ON
HOW TO TALK TO THEM.
WE ARE GOING TO TALK TO A
PSYCHOLOGIST NEXT ABOUT HOW TO
HELP CHILDREN FE SOME OF THE
FEARS THEY MIGHT HAVE IN THE
WAKE OF THE VIOLENCE.
♪
[ Woman ]
♪ WHAT I WANT THIS SEASON
♪ IF YOU'D LIKE
TO TRY AND GUESS ♪
♪ IT IS SOMETHING VERY SPECIAL
♪ I WOULD READILY CONFESS
[ dogs barking ]
♪ 'CAUSE ALL I WANT
THIS SEASON ♪
♪ IS SOMETHING FROM YOUR HEART
♪ LA DA DA, LA DA DA
[ Male Announcer ] THINKING
OF OTHERS THIS HOLIDAY SEASON,
TRAVELERS.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN DIARRHEA HITS,
KAOPECTATE STOPS IT FAST.
POWERFUL LIQUID RELIEF
SPEEDS TO THE SOURCE.
FAST.
[ Male Announcer ]
STOP THE UH-OH FAST
WITH KAOPECTATE.
>>> YOUNG STUDENTS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY PREPARING TO GO BACK TO
SCHOOL FOR THE FIRST TIME SINCE
THE MASSACRE.
SO HOW DO PARENTS DEAL WITH ANY
FEARS THAT THE CHILDREN MAY
HAVE?
DR. CHARLES SEW CITY A
PSYCHIATRIST AND MEDICAL
DIRECTOR FOR THE LOS ANGELES
COUNTY DEPARTMENT OF CHILDREN
AND FAMILY SERVICES.
DR. SOPHIE, THANKS VERY MUCH FOR
COMING IN.
SO WHAT'S THE MOST IMPORTANT
THING PARENTS CAN SAY OR DO TO
ALLEVIATE ANY CONCERNS FOR THESE
YOUNG KIDS?
>> MAKE SURE THEIR EMOTIONAL
RESPONSES ARE INTACT AND THEIR
CHILDREN DON'T BECOME
FRIGHTENED.
YOU NEED TO HAVE THAT
DISCUSSION.
TALK TO THE CHILDREN, ASK THEM
WHAT THEY KNOW.
IF THEY DON'T KNOW ANYTHING,
GIVE THEM AN EDUCATION WHAT
HAPPENED.
NO GORY DETAILS AND THEN LISTEN.
THE KEY IS TO LISTEN TO YOUR
CHILDREN AND THEN ANSWER AGE
APPROPRIATE LIT QUESTIONS.
BUT ANSWERS LESS NEVER SEX MORE
INFORMATION AND LISTEN TO YOUR
CHILDREN.
> HOW DO PARENTS MAKE SURE THEY
DON'T PROJECT THEIR OWN FEARS
ONTO THE KIDS?
>> I THINK THERE'S SEVERAL WAYS
THIS PARENTS CAN PROTECT
THEMSELVES AND NOT WORRY THAT
THEY ARE GOING TO PUT ONTO THEIR
CHILDREN THEIR OWN FEARS AND
CONCERNS AND THESE BY TALKING TO
EACH OTHER AS PARENTS, TALKING
TO OTHER PARENTS AND MAKING SURE
THAT THEY HAVE AT LEAST DEALT
WITH THE FACT THAT THEY CAN
ASSURE SOME SAFETY TO THEIR
CHILDREN AND THAT THEY,
THEMSELVES, FEEL SAFE BUT
DEALING WITH SOME OF THE STUFF
BY TALKING TO OTHER AZULTS THE
ONLY WAY THEY ARE GOING TO BE
ABLE TO ALLEVIATE THEIR OWN
PRESSURES AND GUILT AND FEAR SO
THEY CAN LISTEN TO THEIR
CHILDREN WITHOUT PROJECTING.
>> WHAT ABOUT THE PARENTS
WORKING TOGETHER WITH THEIR
SCHOOLS -- WITH THE CHILDREN'S
SCHOOLS TO MAKE SURE THE KIDS
FEEL SAFE?
WHAT SHOULD THE PARENTS BE
DOING?
>> IT IS IMPORTANT TO GROUP
TOGETHER SO EVERYBODY IS
TALKING, PROCESSING THIS AS A
GROUP SO YOU LIMIT THE ABILITY
FOR RUMORS AND FOR
MISINFORMATION, MISCOMMUNICATION
TO GET OUT THERE AND EVERYBODY
IS ON THE SAME PAGE.
AND YOUR CHILDREN AREN'T COMING
HOME WITH STORIES YOU CAN'T
EXPLAIN.
ALL PARENTS TOGETHER, UNIFIED AS
A COMMUNITY YOU ARE GOING TO BE
BETTER COMMUNICATING TOGETHER
FOR THEIR CHILDREN AND MAKING
MORE STREAMLINED AND CONSISTENT.
AND IT REALLY LIMITS THE ABILITY
FOR PROBLEMS, RUMORS, ANXIETY
AND EVEN MORE EMOTION TO COME
OUT OF THIS.
>> SURE, DOCTOR THERE ARE SOME
PARENTS THOUGHT SAYING TO
THEMSELVES MAYBE I SHOULD KEEP
MY CHILD HOME FROM SCHOOL
TOMORROW THEY ARE AFRAID I GOD
FORBID, OF A COPYCAT OR
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THESE PARENT?
>> I WOULD TELL THEM THAT THOSE
FEELINGS ARE ABSOLUTELY NORMAL
TO HAVE BUT PLEASE DON'T GET
TRAPPED WITHIN THE FEAR OF THAT,
BECAUSE ONCE YOU GIVE INTO THAT,
IT'S GOING TO BE VERY DIFFICULT
TO BREAK THAT BUT I THINK IT'S
IMPORTANT TO DISCUSS WITH YOUR
CHILD, IF YOU THINK THEY ARE
GOING TO BE AFRAID TO SEPARATE
FROM YOU, AND EVEN IF IT'S YOU
AFRAID TO SEPARATE FROM YOUR
CHILD, DO SOME TRANSITIONAL
OBJECT TYPE OF THING.
WRITE A NOTE THEY CAN KEEP WITH
THEM, TAKE A TEDDY BEAR TO
SCHOOL WITH THEM, SOME WAY TO
ALLOW THEM TO STAY CONNECTED TO
YOU EMOTIONALLY AND VICE VERSA
THROUGH THE DAY WILL ALLEVIATE
IT FOR BOTHANT AND CHILD.
>> DR. CHARLES SOPHY, THANKS FOR
THAT GOOD ADVICE, WE APPRECIATE
IT VERY MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
THANKS.
>>> CHECK IN WITH DEBRA,
FEYERICK, SHE HAS OTHER TOP
STORIES MAKING NEWS.
TODAY WE WILL BE BACK HERE IN
JUST A MOMENT WITH MORE OF THE
LATEST FROM THE SCENE.
>>> A SOURCE TELLS CNN THAT
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER HAS
OFFERED TO INCLUDE HIGHER TAX
RATES ON PEOPLE MAKING $1
MILLION IN EXCHANGE FOR
ENTITLEMENT CUTS.
THE WHITE HOUSE IS STILL HOLDING
TO ITS $250,000 THRESHOLD.
UNLESS A DEAL IS REACHED BY
JANUARY 1st PRACTICALLY EVERYONE
WILL BE HIT WITH A TAX INCREASE.
>>> IT APPEARS THAT PRESIDENT
OBAMA HAS TAPPED MASSACHUSETTS
SENATOR JOHN KERRY AS HIS NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE.
A SOURCE SAYS THE PRESIDENT MAY
MAKE THE ANNOUNCEMENT LATER THIS
WEEK.
KERRY NARROWLY LOST THE
PRESIDENT?
I -- PRESIDENCY IN 2004 TO
GEORGE W. BUSH.
HE IS A DECORATED VETERAN OF THE
VIETNAM WAR.
>>> THE STATE DEPARTMENT GETS A
LOOK AT THE DETAILS REPORT ABOUT
THE ATTACK ON THE CONSULATE IN
BENGHAZI, LIBYA.
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON ORDERED THIS REVIEW.
MEMBERS OF CONGRESS ARE
SCHEDULED TO GET THE CLASSIFIED
BRIEFING ON WEDNESDAY.
CLINTON WILL NOT TESTIFY.
SHE IS RECOVERING AFTER A
CONCUSSION FROM FAINTING DUE TO
DEHYDRATION.
>>> AND AS YOU PREPARE TO SEND
YOUR CHILDREN TO SCHOOL
TOMORROW, YOU MAY HAVE TO
ADDRESS SOME FEARS.
OUR NEXT GUEST WILL HELP US FIND
WAYS TO TALK TO OUR CHILDREN
ABOUT TRAGEDY AND LOOK AT WAYS
THAT WE ALL CAN MOVE FORWARD.
From the best
players in history
to the number 1 club
in the world.
The potential of
Manchester United unlocked.
NYSE Euronext.
Unlocking the world's potential.
HOW THEY'LL LIVE TOMORROW.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
>>> EXPLAINING WHAT HAPPENED
HERE IN NEWTOWN TO YOUR CHILDREN
OR TO ANY CHILDREN CAN SEEM LIKE
A DAUNTING TAX, SO AS GROWNUPS,
WE DON'T KNOW HOW TO MAKE SENSE
OUT OF WHAT HAS HAPPENED HERE,
NEVER MIND FOR A YOUNG CHILD.
VIGILS ARE TAKING PLACE AROUND
THE COUNTRY, PEOPLE ARE TRYING
TO UNDERSTAND, TRYING TO
BEGINNING TO HEAL.
FOR CHILDREN THE PROCESS CAN BE
VERY DIFFERENT.
YOU MAY KNOW OUR NEXT GUEST FROM
READING RAIN BOAT.
BRING IN LA VAR BURNT, THE HOST
OF THE PBS CHILDREN'S SERIES.
LA VAR, THANKS FOR TAKING THE
TIME.
A LOT OF PARENTS I KNOW SAID SO
FAR THIS WEEKEND, HAVEN'T TOLD
MY CHILDREN, I HAVE KEPT THEM
AWAY FROM MEDIA AND AWAY FROM
TELEVISION BECAUSE I DIDN'T IS
KNOW HOW TO TELL THEM IF I
SHOULD TELL THEM.
FOR THOSE PARENTS, SHOULD THEY
TELL THEIR CHILDREN BECAUSE THEY
COULD HEAR FROM PARENTS OR
TEACHERS?
WHAT DO YOU DO?
>> WITHOUT QUESTION.
ERIN, THANK YOU AND WOLF FOR THE
OPPOUNITY TO BE HERE.
GRATED CHILD PSYCHOLOGIST ON IN
THE PREVIOUS SEGMENT, NOT A
CHILD PSYCHOLOGIST BUT I SPEND A
LOT OF TIME COMMUNICATING WITH
KIDS AND THE EXPERTS SAY, YES,
IT IS IMPORTANT FOR YOU AS A
PARENT TO GET OUT IN FRONT OF
THIS MESS.
AN YOU CONTROL THE MESS ARMS IF
YOU DON'T, AS SOON AS THEY HIT
SCHOOL TOMORROW, IT IS GOING TO
BE CONTROLLED BY KIDS WHO ARE
JUST A LITTLE OLDER THAN THEY
ARE, YOUR CHILDREN.
SO, TAKE THE TIME TONIGHT AND I
KNOW THAT IT'S -- IT'S
UNCOMFORTABLE, ESPECIALLY WHEN
WE, AS PARENTS, ARE STILL TRYING
TO PROCESS THIS OURSELVES.
SO, WE HAVE TO HAVE THE COURAGE
TO REALLY HAVE THAT DIFFICULT
CONVERSATION WITH OUR KIDS AND
TO, IN AN AGE-APPROPRIATE WAY.
AND YOU KNOW YOUR KIDS BETTER
THAN ANYBODY IN TERMS OF WHAT
THEY CAN HANDLE AND WHAT'S THE
RIGHT LANGUAGE TO USE, WHAT'S
THE RIGHT FRAMING FOR THIS THING
THAT HAS HAPPENED TO ALL OF US,
AND LISTENING TO YOUR KIDS IS
REALLY, REALLY IMPORTANT.
>> LEVAR TO THAT, WHEN YOU TALK
ABOUT LISTENING TO YOUR KIDS YOU
CAN WOLF AND I WERE TALKING
MOMENTS AGO, YOU TELL SOME
CHILDREN, THEY MAY BE SILENT AND
STOIC AND MAY BE BECAUSE THEY
ARE BOLTING IT UP INSIDE,
WHETHER THEY ARE AFRAID OUR
UPSET BUT OTHER KIDS MAY TRULY
NOT BE THAT AFFECTED BY T AS A
PARENT IT IS SO HARD TO KNOW
WHICH CATEGORY YOUR CHILD FALL
NEWS.
HOW DO YOU TRY GET THE TONE
RIGHT AND NOT TAKE A CHILD WHO
SUSPECT AFRAID AND MAKE THEM
BECOME AFRAID?
>> IT'S DEMOCRATS, ISN'T IT?
AS MUCH AS WE WANT TO GO AND HUG
OUR KIDS YOU THAT, IS THE THING
TO DO NOW, TAKE SOME TIME TO
PROCESS YOUR SSELF AS PARENTS.
TRUTHFULLY, TAKE A BATH, REALLY.
I MEAN, DURING TIMES OF TRAUMA,
WATER SEEMS TO HELP.
NOT JUST A SHOWER, I'M TALKING
ABOUT -- GUYS, I HAVE DONE THE
SAME THING, I HAVE IMMERSED
MYSELF IN WATER TODAY TO HELP ME
PROCESS WHAT I JUST DON'T SEEM
TO HAVE A WAY TO UNDERSTAND.
AND SO I WOULD RECOMMEND, YOU
KNOW, BATHE YOUR KIDS.
THROW THEM IN THE TUB AND MAKE
SURE YOU GET A BATH YOURSELF.
AND ALLOW YOURSELF TO REALLY
FEEL WHAT YOU'RE FEELING AND
KNOW THAT YOUR KIDS ARE FEELING
IT, TOO AND LET THEM BE THE
GUIDE.
TAKE THE CUES FROM THEM.
BUT IF YOU'VE GOT ONE THAT'S
REALLY SILENT AND STOIC IT IS
IMPORTANT TO SORT OF SOUND THEM
OUT ON WHAT THEY KNOW, WHAT THEY
ARE AWARE OF AND HOW THEY FEEL
ABOUT IT, BECAUSE IT'S GOING TO
BE THE NATIONAL COVER WAS ON
PLAYGROUNDS, IN OFFICE
BUILDINGS, IN SCHOOLS, IN
AMERICA, FOR DAYS TO COME.
>> BECAUSE, LEVAR, WE GOT TO
MAKE SURE OUR CHILDREN KNOW
THEY'RE SAFE.
SO WHAT'S BEST WAY TO
COMMUNICATE THAT TO THE KIDS?
>> WELL, I'M ALL FOR LETTING
THEM KNOW THAT THE PERSON
RESPONSIBLE FOR THIS IS NO
LONGER A THREAT TO ANYONE.
WE, THE ADULTS IN THE WORLD ARE
TAKING CARE OF ALL THE THINGS
THAT NEED TO BE TAKEN CARE OF IN
TERMS OF THE AFTERMATH OF THIS,
BUT THEY NEED TO KNOW THAT THEY
ARE SAFE AND THAT THEY ARE GOING
TO CONTINUE TO BE SAFE.
I RECOMMEND A LOT OF HUGS.
SIT AND READ WITH YOUR KIDS.
IT'S A GREAT WAY TO PASS THIS
TIME.
ONCE, YOU KNOW, I'M LOVING THE
FACT THAT A LOT OF FAMILIES
AROUND THE COUNTRY ARE REALLY
LIMITING THEIR CHILDREN'S
EXPOSURE AND OWN EXPOSURE TO THE
NEWS COVERAGE.
WE HAVE TO TAKE BREAKS FROM IT.
IT'S REALLY EASY TO BECOME
ABSOLUTELY SATURATED AND
OVERWHELMED BY IT.
SO, THESE ARE ALL GOOD THING TO
US REMEMBER.
MOST OF ALL, WE HAVE TO JUST
REMEMBER TO BE GENT WELL
OURSELVES AND EACH OTHER FOR A
WHILE.
ALL SORT OF WALKING AROUND OPEN
WOUNDS.
>> ARE THERE POSITIVE WAYS TO
ADDRESS THIS TRANG GUY CHILDREN,
PERHAPS WHEN THE CHILDREN ASK
QUESTIONS ABOUT THE OTHER
CHILDREN, WHEN THEY ASK
QUESTIONS ABOUT THOSE 6 AND
7-YEAR-OLDS?
>> IT IS ALWAYS APPROPRIATE TO
ACKNOWLEDGE THE FEELINGS OF
CHILDREN A LOT OF WHAT I KNOW I
LEARNED FROM THE MASTER, FRED
ROGERS, HE WAS ALWAYS ONE FOR
MEETING KIDS WHERE THEY ARE AND
THAT'S SOMETHING THAT WE CAN ALL
DO.
AND DON'T FORGET THOSE HUGS.
>> HOW HAS THE TRAGEDY AFFECT
YOU HAD PERSONALLY?
>> IT'S DIFFICULT.
I'M HAVING A HARD TIME WITH IT.
I REALLY AM.
I'M HAVING A HARD TIME.
AND I THINK BEING ABLE TO
EXPRESS MYSELF ON IT HELPS AN
AWFUL LOT.
WE -- WE ARE ALL EXPERIENCING
THIS TOGETHER AND WE ARE IN
UNCHARTERED TERRITORY HERE, SO
IN THIS MOMENT, I'M -- I FEEL
LIKE I'M HELPING AND SO I AM
A -- I FEEL LIKE I'M, YOU KNOW,
I'M FINE.
I'M FUNCTIONAL, BUT I KNOW AT
THE SAME TIME, I'M ALTERED.
I'M DIFFERENT TODAY THAN I WAS
YESTERDAY.
>> NOT JUST YOU, I THINK ALL OF
US FEEL EXACTLY THE SAME WAY.
I THINK YOU'RE SPEAKING FOR A
LOT OF PEOPLE AND I SUSPECT THAT
WHEN WE HEAR FROM THE PRESIDENT
TONIGHT AT THIS INTERFAITH VIGIL
RIGHT HERE IN CONNECTICUT, HE
WILL BE MAKING SOME OF THOSE
SAME POINTS.
LEVAR BURTON, THANKS VERY MUCH
FOR WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
THANKS VERY MUCH FOR JOINING US.
>> THANKS, WOLF.
>> THE PRESIDENT WROTE HIS
SPEECH VIRTUALLY ALL HIMSELF,
NOT RELYING ON SPEECHWRITERS OR
ANYTHING LIKE THAT TONIGHT.
>> I SUSPECT ALSO, AS A FATHER,
AS OPPOSED TO BEING PRESIDENT.
HE KNOWS HE HAS TO COMFORT THE
NATION RIGHT NOW, THAT IS HIS
RESPONSIBILITY, BUT HE IS ALSO
SPEAKING FROM THE HEART AS THE
FATHER OF TWO GIRLS.
>>> WE DO HAVE NEW INFORMATION
ABOUT HOW THE SUSPECTED GUNMAN
GOT INTO THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE JUST FOUND THAT OUT A FEW
MOMENTS AGO FROM THE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE AND ABOUT THE
WEAPONS HE USED IN THE RAMPAGE.
THAT'S NEXT.
SantHo, Ho, Ho!anta!
Santa!
Want to see some magic?
Watch this! Merry Chr...
(Crash) Ow!
I landed on my keys.
Did you get that?
Oh yeah.
That was amazing.
Here you go.
That was a fun trick!
See? Santa's okay.
Walk it off Santa.
Share videos instantly
with S Beam.
On the Galaxy SIII
and Note II.
For a limited time get two flip
covers for the price of one.
Exclusively at Verizon.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS KAREN AND JEREMIAH.
THEY DON'T KNOW IT YET,
BUT THEY'RE GONNA FALL IN LOVE,
GET MARRIED,
HAVE A COUPLE OF KIDS,
[ children laughing ]
MOVE TO THE COUNTRY,
AND LIVE A LONG, HAPPY LIFE
TOGETHER
WHERE THEY ALMOST NEVER FIGHT
ABOUT MONEY.
[ dog barks ]
BECAUSE RIGHT AFTER
THEY GET MARRIED,
THEY'LL FIND
SOME RETIREMENT PEOPLE
WHO ARE PAID ON SALARY,
NOT COMMISSION.
THEY'LL GET
STRAIGHTFORWARD GUIDANCE
AND BE ABLE TO FOCUS ON OTHER
THINGS, LIKE EACH OTHER,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
>>> WELCOME BACK.
WE ARE HERE FOLLOWING THE
AFTERMATH OF THE HORRIFIC,
HORRIFIC TRAGEDY THAT HAPPENED
FRIDAY MORNING, 9:30 A.M. FRIDAY
MORNING, ALL OF A SUDDEN SO A
MANY LIVES CHANGED AND MILLIONS
OF PEOPLE AROUND THE WORLD, I
THINK THEIR LIVES CHANGED AS
WELL.
>> WOLF, AT THAT MOMENT, I WAS
OVERSEAS AND I THOUGHT THAT IT
WAS A TYPO AS I'M SURE MANY
PEOPLE DID THAT IT WAS
IMPOSSIBLE TO COMP PREHELPED
THAT MY WAY BACK, THERE WAS
PEOPLE AROUND EVERY TV SCREEN,
WATCHING CNN.
>> YOU WERE IN AFGHANISTAN WITH
THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE?
>> YES.
>> ALL OF A SUDDEN, YOU THINK
THERE'S VIOLENCE THERE THERE
AND'S HORRIFIC VIOLENCE RIGHT
HERE IN CONNECTICUT WHEN YOU
THINK ABOUT IT.
>> YES.
>> POLICE IN NOOUNT HERE IN
CONNECTICUT JUST WRAPPED UP A
NEWS CONFERENCE ON THE MASS
SHOOTING OF THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL FRIDAY
MORNING.
HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW RIGHT NOW
INVESTIGATORS SAY THE SUSPECTED
GUNMAN, THE 20-YEAR-OLD, ADAM
LANZA, FIRED HUNDREDS OF
BULLETS, YES, HUNDREDS OF BILLS
FROM MULTIPLE MAGAZINE HE IS
FROM A BUSHMASTER ASSAULT-STYLE
WEAPON.
THEY ALSO SAY THAT THE ASSAULT
WEAPON WAS MAIN WEAPON USED IN
THIS ATTACK, IN THIS MASS
MURDER.
POLICE ALSO SAY THE SUSPECT'S
MOTHER, NANCY LANZA, SHE DIED OF
WHAT THEY ARE SAYING NOW
MULTIPLE GUNSHOT WOUNDS, NOT
JUST ONE, MULTIPLE GUNSHOT
WOUNDS AND THEY REPORT THAT ADAM
LANZA DIED OF A SELF-INFLICTED
GUNSHOT WOUND HIMSELF.
>> THE PRESIDENT IS EXPECTED TO
ARRIVE IN NEWTOWN ANY MINUTE
NOW.
WE KNOW THAT HE HAS ARRIVED IN
HARTFORD, HE JUST TOUK TOUCHED
DOWN IN CONNECT CONNECT,
LITERALLY, WOLF, 30 MINUTES AGO
IN A MOTORCADE COMING HERE,
UNABLE TO TAKE A HELICOPTER
BECAUSE OF THE INCLEMENT WLCHLT
HE WILL BE MEETING WITH FAMILIES
AND FIRST RESPONDERS, HE WILL BE
SPEAKING AT AN INTERFAITH VIGIL,
THE SPEECH, WE CAN TELL YOU, HE
WROTE HIMSELF.
WE WILL BRING THAT SERVICE TO
YOU LIVE IN ITS ENTIRETY.
BEGIN AT 7:30 EASTERN TIME AND
EXPECTED TO LAST, WOLF, 90
MINUTES.
>> YESTERDAY, I DID MEET WITH
THE MINISTER, A RAN BIND OTHERS
WHO ARE LEADING THIS VIGIL AND
THEY ARE GRATEFUL THAT THE
PRESIDENT DECIDED IN HIS ROLE AS
WHAT WE CALL COMFORTER AND CHIEF
TO COME HERE, NOT ONLY SPEAK
PUBLICLY AND ADDRESS THE PEOPLE
HERE BUT ADDRESS THE NATION AND
THE WORLD AND ALSO MEETING
PRIVATELY WITH FAMILY MEMBERS,
WITH FIRST RESPONDERS AND
OTHERS.
>> THIS IS IS A MOMENT OF GRIEF
THAT EVERYONE'S FEELING, A HOLE
AND AN EMPTINESS.
GET TO DEBRA, FEYERICK IN
ATLANTA FOR SOME OF THE OTHER
MAJOR STORIES WE ARE FOLLOWING
ON THIS AFTERNOON.
>>> A FRIGHTENING INCIDENT FOR
SHOPPERS AT A MALL PARKING NOT
NEWPORT BEACH.
[ GUNFIRE ]
NO ONE WAS HIT BUT ONE PERSON
DID SUFFER MINOR INJURIES TRYING
TO GET OUT OF THE AREA.
THE SUSPECT IS IN CUSTODY.
POLICE IS GIVEN NO REASON FOR
THE SHOOTING.
>>> IN EGYPT, THE MUSLIM
BROTHERHOOD DECLARES A NARROW
VICTORY IN THE FIRST ROUND OF A
HOTLY CONTESTED CONSTITUTIONAL
REFERENDUM THIS IS ON THE FIRST
WEEK OF VOTING.
THE REST OF THE COUNTRY IS
EXPECTED TO VOTE NEXT WEEKEND.
ELECTION MONITORS REPORT SOME
CLAIMS OF VOTER INTIMIDATION AND
ALSO EARLY POLL CLOSINGS.
>>> IN LONDON, THE DUCHESS OF
CAME BRIDGE IS ATTENDING HER
FIRST PUBLIC ENGAGEMENT SINCE
HER PREGNANCY WAS ANNOUNCED THIS
MONTH.
A SPOKESMAN SAYS KATHERINE IS TO
APPEAR AT THE BBC'S SPORTS
PERSONALITY OF THE YEAR AWARDS
TONIGHT.
SHE WAS LAST SEEN DECEMBER 6th
LEAVING THE HOSPITAL AFTER
SEVERAL DAYS OF TREATMENT FOR
ACUTE MORNING SICKNESS.
>>> THERE'S LOTS MORE NEWS
COMING UP, BUT RIGHT NOW, WE
WANT TO GO BACK TO WOLF BLITZER,
HE IS IN NEWTOWN.
AND WOLF, YOU ARE TALKING ABOUT
HEALING AND THIS SERVICE TONIGHT
AND PEOPLE JUST NEED SO MUCH
TIME TO JUST WRAP THEIR HEAD
AROUND WHAT HAS HAPPENED THERE.
>> HARD TO BELIEVE WHAT
HAPPENED.
I HAVE BEEN HERE NOW A COUPLE
DAYS, DEB, AND I'M NOT EVEN SURE
I UNDERSTAND COMPLETELY THE
ENORMITY OF THIS HUGE, HUGE
TRAGEDY, A VERY, VERY SAD STORY
FROM A TO.
>> AND I SUSPECT IT'S -- AS WE
GET MORE AND MORE DETAILS, IT
WILL JUST BECOME EVEN MORE
SHOCKING.
THE SHOOTINGS HERE AT THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HAVE
RESPARKED ALSO THE DEBATE ACROSS
THE COUNTRY OVER GUN CONTROL IN
AMERICA.
TODAY, LAWMAKERS TOOK TO THE AIR
WAVES ON THE SUNDAY TALK SHOWS
TO ARGUE BOTH SIDES OF THE
CONTROVERSY.
>> IT'S SO UNBELIEVABLE AND IT
ONLY HAPPENS IN AMERICA.
AND IT HAPPENS AGAIN AND AGAIN.
KILL THEM IN HOSPITALS WE KILL
THEM IN RELIGIOUS ORGANIZATIONS,
WE KILL THEM WHEN THEY ARE
YOUNG, WE KILL THEM WHEN THEY'RE
OLD AND WE JUST GOT TO STOP
THIS.
IT'S TIME FOR THE PRESIDENT, I
THINK, TO STAND UP AND LEAD AND
TELL THIS COUNTRY WHAT WE SHOULD
DO.
>> I'M GOING TO INTRODUCE IN THE
SENATE AND THE SAME BILL WILL BE
INTRODUCED IN THE HOUSE, A BILL
TO BAN ASSAULT WEAPONS, BUT THE
PURPOSE OF THIS BILL IS TO GET
JUST WHAT MAYOR BLOOMBERG SAID,
WEAPONS OF WAR OFF THE STREET.
>> I OWN A GLOCK 23, I HAVE GOT
A SHOTGUN, I AM NOT THE PERSON
YOU NEED WORRY ABOUT AND THERE
ARE MILLIONS OF AMERICANS WHO
DEAL WITH THIS PROPERLY.
IT IS OUR SECOND AMENDMENT RIGHT
TO DO SO.
BUT WE HAVE TO LOOK AT THE
MENTAL HEALTH ACCESS.
>> THESE ARE ASSAULT WEAPONS,
YOU DON'T HUNT DEER WITH THESE
THINGS.
AND I THINK THAT'S THE QUESTION
A LOT OF PEOPLE HAVE TO RESOLVE
IN THEIR OWN MINDS WHERE SHOULD
THIS LINE GET DRAWN?
>> EVERY MASS KILLING OF MORE
THAN THREE PEOPLE IN RECENT
HISTORY HAS BEEN IN A PLACE
WHERE GUNS WERE PROHIBITED AND
HEARING THE HEROIC STORIES OF
THE PRINCIPAL LUNGING, TRYING TO
PROTECT CHRIS, I WISH TO GOD SHE
HAD HAD AN M-4 IN HER OFFICE
LOCKED UP SO WHEN SHE HEARD
GUNFIRE, SHE PULLS IT OUT AND
SHE DIDN'T HAVE TO LUNGE
HEROICALLY WITH NOTHING IN HER
HANDS, BUT SHE TAKES HIM OUT,
HIS HEAD OFF BEFORE HE CAN KILL
THOSE PRECIOUS KIDS.
>> I HONESTLY THINK THAT THAT
ARGUMENT JUST DOESN'T HOLD
WATER.
WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT IT, ARE WE
TALKING ABOUT ARMING PRINCIPALS,
ARMING TEACHERS?
IS THAT GOING TO MAKE US A SAFER
AMERICA?
I DON'T THINK.
>> SO >> PRESIDENT OBAMA'S
PROMISING TO TAKE SOME ACTION.
RIGHT NOW IT'S UNCLEAR WHAT HE
IS GOING TO DO BUT THE PRESSURE
CERTAINLY WILL MOUNT IN THE
COMING DAYS, WEEKS AND MONTHS.
AS THE PEOPLE HERE IN NEWTOWN
TRY TO COME TO TERMS WITH THEIR
GRIEF, CAN RELIGION PROVIDE
COMFORT?
A BIBLE EXPERT WILL SHOW US WHAT
RELIGIOUS SCRIPTURE HAS TO
OFFER.
YO, GIVE IT UP, DUDE!
UP HIGH!
OK. DON'T YOU HAVE
ANY USEFULL APPS ON THAT THING?
WHO DO YOU THINK I AM,
Quicken Loans?
♪
AT Quicken Loans,
OUR AMAZINGLY USEFUL
MORTGAGE CALCULATOR APP
ALLOWS YOU TO QUICKLY CALCULATE
YOUR MORTGAGE PAYMENT
BASED ON TODAY'S INCREDIBLY LOW
INTEREST RATES...
RIGHT FROM YOUR IPHONE
OR ANDROID SMARTPHONE.
ONE MORE WAY Quicken Loans
IS ENGINEERED TO AMAZE.
♪
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
>>> THIS TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN HAS
BROUGHT PEOPLE TOGETHER TO MOURN
AND TO COMFORT ONE ANOTHER,
THROUGH WORDS AND MEMORIALS, WE
ARE FEELING THE HEARTFELT
EMOTIONS FLOWING THROUGH THIS
TOWN, NOT JUST THIS TOWN, BUT
AROUND THE COUNTRY.
>> DIED DOING WHAT YOU LOVE,
PROTECT THE KIDS.
FIRST WE START OFF WITH A MOMENT
OF SILENCE.
>> GIVE USER IS REHNITY TO
ENDURE WHAT SOMETIMES MAY BE
UNBEARABLE.
>> I WANT TO TELL PEOPLE TO KEEP
FAITH IN GOD BECAUSE AT THESE
TI
TIMES, IT IS NECESSARY.
>> I THOUGHT I SHOULD COME.
>> THAT MUSIC "YOU WILL NEVER
WALK ALONE."
THE KILLING OF SO MANY INNOCENT
CHILDREN AND THEIR TEACHERS HAS
GENERATED LOTS OF GRIEF AND
ANGER, THESE POWERFUL FEELINGS
EXTEND BEYOND THE CITY OF
NEWTOWN.
ASSOCIATE PROFESSOR OF EMORY
UNIVERSITY'S CHANDLER SCHOOL OF
THEOLOGY IS HERE TO TALK ABOUT
HOW RELIGIOUS TEXT CAN PROVIDE
SOME COMFORT, ESPECIALLY IF THIS
HOLIDAY SEASON.
THANKS SO MUCH FOR BEING HERE.
LET'S TALK ABOUT GRIEF AND JOY
AND HOW THEY ARE LINKED SO
TIGHTLY SOMETIMES.
>> THE BIBLE IS FULL OF TEXT
THAT LINKS GRIEF AND SORROW AND
THAT TRY TO WORK THROUGH THOSE
ON THE WAY TO JOY AND HAPPINESS
IT IS SOLD SELE DOM AN EASY
ROAD.
>> WE LEAK AT GRIEF, SORROW IT
IS ABOUT VULNERABILITY, ABOUT SO
MANY PEOPLE FEELING JUST SO
CLOSE TO THE EDGE.
WHAT DOES THE BUY BIBLE TELL US
ABOUT WALKING THROUGH IT, TO THE
LIGHT?
>> IN MATTHEW, THE NEW
TESTAMENT, JESUS' BIRTH IS
ACCOMPANIED BY THE SLAUGHT OVER
CHILDREN, KING HERROD SO
FRIGHTENED OF JESUS, KILLS ALL
THE CHILDREN IN BETHLEHEM UP TO
2 YEARS OF AIM T IS THE
SLAUGHTER OF THE HOLY INNOCENTS
AND THE EVIL DONE, EVEN AT
CHRISTMASTIME.
>> YOU QUESTION HOW CAN THIS
EVIL EXIST IN THE WORLD,
SOMETHING THAT'S SO SENSELESS,
THAT NORMAL PEOPLE CAN'T
COMPREHEND THE DEPTH OVER THE
EVIL.
WHAT DOES THE BIBLE SAY?
>> THE BIBLE IS FULL OF TEXTS
THAT ARTICULATE THIS GRIEF AND
SORROW OVER TRAN DITCH THE
PSALMS PROBABLY THE MOST
ARTICULATE EXPRESSIONS OF THOSE,
LIKE MY GOD, MY GOD WHY HAVE YOU
FORSAKEN ME, WHY ARE YOU SO FAR
FROM MY GROANING, THE WORDS OF
MYING AN LISH WITH FISH?
THE BIBLE SHOWS THROUGH PSALMS
THAT PEOPLE ARE HO ARE RELIGIOUS
FILL THE FULL EMOTIONAL WEIGHT
ASSOCIATED WITH TRAGEDY AND THEY
PRAY IN THAT TRAGEDY BECAUSE
THEY NEED HELP.
AND THE PRAYERS ALSO SHOW THAT
THEY FREQUENTLY -- THAT THOSE
PRAYERS FREQUENTLY HELP, THAT
THE PSALMS END FREQUENTLY IN
HOPE AND CONFIDENCE ACRES
FIRMING THAT GOD HASN'T DESPISED
THOSE WHO SUFFER BUT LISTENED TO
THEM AND ATTENDED TO THEM AND
HELPED THEM.
>> THERE IS THAT QUESTION THAT
SO MANY PEOPLE ASK AT A TIME
LIKE THIS.
AND THAT IS HOW COULD THIS
HAPPEN?
HOW COULD GOT GOD LESS THIS
>> NO EASY ANTICIPATE TO THAT
QUESTION.
ALL RELIGIONS TRY TO DEAL WITH
THE PROBLEM OF SUFFERING AND
EVIL ONE WAY OR THE OTHER.
BUT I THINK THE BIBLE HOLDS
PRECIOUS SEVERAL CONVICTIONS.
ONE IS GOD IS WITH US WHEN WE
SUFFER.
ANOTHER IS GOD REALLY KNOWS OUR
SUFFERING, LISTENENS TO IT, SEE
IT IS, EXPERIENCES IT, SOMEHOW
HELP US THROUGH IT MAYBE
PRECISELY THROUGH THESE TOOLS OF
PRAYER AND TEXTS LIKE THE
PSALMS, BUT THERE ARE TWO OTHER
THINGS I THINK THE BIBLE IS
HELPFUL ON IN THIS POINT.
ONE IS THAT THE BIBLE CONTAINS
THE HOPE THAT ONE DAY YOU GOD
WILL SET THE WORLD STRAIGHT.
AND IT'S EXACTLY EVENTS LIKE
THIS THAT LEAD TO THAT
CONVICTION AND THAT HOPE THAT WE
ALL NEED AND WANT TO LIVE IN A
WORLD WHERE NONE OF THIS EVER
HAPPENS AGAIN.
THE OTHER THING THE BIBLE SAYS
IS THAT IN THE MEAN TIME, WE
HAVE A LOT OF WORK TO DO TO HELP
GOD SET THE WORLD STRAIGHT U AND
THAT WORK INCLUDES COMFORTING
THOSE WHO MOURN AND ALSO DOING
WHATEVER WE CAN TO CONTAIN
VIOLENCE AND RESTRICT IT AND
RESTRICT EVIL SO THAT NONE OF US
HAVE TO MOURN LIKE WE DO NOW.
>> EVERY GOOD DEED, EVERY EVIL
ACT A WAY TO REPAIR A BROKEN
WORLD.
BRENT STRAWN, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH, THANK YOU FOR BEING WUSS
WUSS AT A DIFFICULT TIME WHEN
PEOPLE ARE LOOKING FOR WORDS OF
COMFORT, LOOKING FOR WAYS TO
COME TOGETHER AND UNITE AND NOT
FEEL AS IF THEY WALK ALONE.
THANK YOU, APPRECIATE IT.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> CONNECTICUT POLICE LASH OUT
AGAINST WHAT THEY CALL CRIMES
BEING COMMITTED ON SOCIAL MEDIA
INVOLVING THEIR INVESTIGATION.
WHAT ARE THOSE CRIMES?
WE WILL FIND OUT.
[ Male Announcer ] Alka-Seltzer
Plus PRESENTS THE Cold Truth.
I HAVE A COLD,
AND I TOOK NYQUIL,
BUT I'M STILL "STUBBED" UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT DOESN'T HAVE A DECONGESTANT.
NO WAY.
[ Male Announcer ] SORRY.
Alka-Seltzer Plus FIGHTS
YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A FAST ACTING
DECONGESTANT
TO RELIEVE YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
[ sighs ] THANKS!
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus.
♪ OH
WHAT A RELIEF IT IS! ♪
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
AND SAVE $1
VISIT Alka-Seltzer ON FACEBOOK.
>>> A STERN WARPING FROM
CONNECTICUT POLICE TODAY ABOUT
SOCIAL MEDIA.
THEY SAY SOME POSTS ARE FALSE
AND EVEN THREATENING AND
AUTHORITIES SAY THEY WILL LEVS
STORY.
>> LISTEN TO WHAT POLICE SAID.
>> THIS INFORMATION IS BEING
POSTED ON SOCIAL MEDIA SITES.
THERE HAS BEEN MISINFORMATION
COMING FROM PEOPLE POSING AS THE
SHOOTER IN THIS CASE, POSING --
USING HER I.D.s, MIMICKING THIS
CRIME AND CRIME SCENE AND
CRIMINAL ACTIVE THAT TOOK PLACE
IN THIS COMMUNITY THERE HAVE
BEEN SOME THINGS IN SOMEWHAT OF
A THREATENING AMERICAN.
IT IS IMPORTANT TO KNOW THAT WE
HAVE DISCUSSED WITH FEDERAL
AUTHORITIES THAT THESE -- THESE
ISSUES ARE CRIMES.
THEY WILL BE INVESTIGATED
STATEWIDE AND FEDERALLY AND
PROSECUTION WILL TAKE PLACE WHEN
PEOPLE PERPETRATING THIS
INFORMATION ARE IDENTIFIED.
>> THERE COULD BE SOME REAL NEW
LEGAL STEPS WE HAVEN'T SEEP
BEFORE AND THIS RAISES A LOT OF
QUESTIONS.
I WANT YOU-ALL TO KNOW WE DON'T
KNOW WHICH POSTS THEY ARE
TALKING B WE HAVE ALL SEEP,
THOSE OF US WHO COVER THIS, HAVE
SEEN SOME POSTS OUT THERE THAT
ARE OR APPEAR TO BE FAKE.
NOT GOING TO CONJECTURE WHICH
THEY ARE TALKING ABOUT, BECAUSE
AUTHORITIES WON'T SAY.
WHEN DO YOU CROSS THE LINE INTO
SOMETHING DOING SOMETHING
ILLEGAL?
TO ANSWER THAT I REACHED OUT TO
A CYBERLAW EXPERT.
>> SAYING THINGS ABOUT THE
CONNECTICUT SHOOTING SOMEWHAT IN
A THREATENING MANNER THAT IS NOT
GOING TO BE ACTIONABLE, FOR THE
MOST PART.
IF YOU INTENTIONALLY INTERFERE
WITH AN INVESTIGATION, MISLEAD
OFFICERS TRYING TO CONDUCT AN
INVESTIGATION ON PURPOSE, WELL
THEN, YEAH ABSOLUTELY, YOU'RE
GOING TO BE PROSECUTED.
ANOTHER IS WHERE YOU
INTENTIONALLY CREATE A PUBLIC
PANIC.
BUT UNDERSTAND WHAT THE
PROSECUTION WOULD HAVE TO SHOW
IS THE POST OR THE TWEET OR
WHATEVER IT HAPPENS TO BE WAS
DONE INTENTIONALLY, ON PURPOSE,
IN ORDER TO INTERFERE WITH THE
INVESTIGATION IN ORDER TO CREATE
A PUBLIC PANIC AND IS A
RELATIVELY HIGH BAR TO SHOW.
>> THAT WAS RYAN CALEB, A LAW
PR
PROFESSOR WITH THE UNIVERSITY OF
WASHINGTON AND STANFORD'S
INTERNET AND SOCIETY.
I WANT TO TURN THE WHEEL A
LITTLE BIT AND TELL YOU-ALL AT
THE SAME TIME THAT SOCIAL MEDIA
IS A CENTRAL POINT OF DISCUSSION
AND NOW PART OF THE STORY.
IN THE WAKE OF WHAT HAPPENED,
ONE THING YOU ARE SEEING IS A
LOT OF PEOPLE DEBATING GUN LAWS
NOW ON FACE BOOK AND ON TWITTER
AND WHAT SHOULD BE DONE ABOUT
PEOPLE WHO HAVE MENTAL ILLNESS.
SOCIAL MEDIA IS ALSO GIVING
PEOPLE A VOICE AND IN SOME WAYS,
THAT WAY, WOLF, DOING A A LOT OF
GOOD, LETTING PEOPLE VOICE THEIR
VIEWS.
FORCE WHAT THE CRIMES ARE WE ARE
GOING TO STAY ALL OVER THIS,
WOLF, AND FIND OUT WHAT IT IS
THAT AUTHORITIES ARE LOOKING TO
CRACKDOWN THERE.
>> JEFF LEVELS, THANKS FOR THAT
REPORT.
>>> HERE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECT
CONNECT, WE ARE ALL GRIEVING FOR
THE FLAMES OF THESE VICTIMS.
From the best
players in history
to the number 1 club
in the world.
The potential of
Manchester United unlocked.
NYSE Euronext.
Unlocking the world's potential.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
>>> TRAGEDY HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, BROUGHT PEOPLE
TOGETHER, TOGETHER IN THEIR
GRIEF TO MOURN.
FAMILIES WHO WERE AFFECTED AND
EVEN THE MEDIA, WE ALL FEEL THIS
>> JUST TRYING TO COMFORT EACH
OTHER DURING THESE DIFFICULT
TIMES THROUGH WORDS, MEMORIALS.
WE ARE ALL FEELING THE HEARTFELT
EMOTION FLOWING THROUGH THIS
TOWN AND INDEED, AROUND THE
COUNTRY.
AS WE END THIS HOUR, WE WANT TO
PAY TRIBUTE TO THOSE WHO LOST
THEIR LIVES WAY TOO SOON.
>> JUST A TRAGIC, TRAGIC
SITUATION FOR THE TEACHERS, THE
PRINCIPALS, AND THOSE ANSWER
GEMS.
THAT'S ALL I KEEP THINKING ABOUT
IS THOSE ANGELS.
>> I MEAN, WHEN THINGS HAPPEN TO
YOUR CHILDREN, OTHER PEOPLE, I
CAN'T LOOK AT MY CHILDREN'S
FACES NOW WITHOUT SEEING THE
FACES OF EVERY ONE OF THEIR
SCHOOLMATES.
[ Male Announcer ] THIS IS
JOE WOODS' FIRST DAY OF WORK.
AND HIS NEW BOSS TOLD HIM
TWO THINGS --
COOK WHAT YOU LOVE,
AND SAVE YOUR MONEY.
JOE DOESN'T KNOW IT YET,
BUT HE'LL WORK HIS WAY UP
FROM BUSSER TO WAITER TO CHEF
BEFORE OPENING A RESTAURANT
SPECIALIZING IN FISH AND GAME
FROM THE GREAT NORTHWEST.
HE'LL START INVESTING EARLY,
HE'LL FIND SOME GOOD PEOPLE
TO HELP GUIDE HIM,
AND HE'LL SET MONEY ASIDE
FROM HIS FIRST DAY OF WORK
TO HIS LAST,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
YOU'LL ALSO CARE ABOUT
OUR NEW OFFER.
YOU GET ACCESS TO NURSES WHO
CAN HELP WITH YOUR QUESTIONS.
AND YOUR LOVED ONE CAN GET
EXELON PATCH FREE FOR 30 DAYS.
IF THE DOCTOR FEELS
IT'S RIGHT FOR THEM.
IT CANNOT CHANGE
HOW THE DISEASE PROGRESSES.
HOSPITALIZATION
AND RARELY DEATH
HAVE BEEN REPORTED IN PATIENTS
WHO WORE MORE THAN ONE PATCH
AT A TIME.
THE MOST COMMON SIDE EFFECTS
OF EXELON PATCH
ARE NAUSEA, VOMITING,
AND DIARRHEA.
THE LIKELIHOOD AND SEVERITY
OF THESE SIDE EFFECTS
MAY INCREASE
AS THE DOSE INCREASES.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
LOSS OF APPETITE OR WEIGHT.
PATIENTS WHO WEIGH
LESS THAN 110 POUNDS
MAY EXPERIENCE
MORE SIDE EFFECTS.
PEOPLE AT RISK
FOR STOMACH ULCERS
WHO TAKE CERTAIN
OTHER MEDICINES
SHOULD TALK TO THEIR DOCTOR
BECAUSE SERIOUS
STOMACH PROBLEMS
SUCH AS BLEEDING MAY WORSEN.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
SLOW HEART RATE.
THIRTY DAYS OF EXELON PATCH
FREE FOR YOUR LOVED ONE.