WITNESSED, THOSE CHILDREN WHO
SAW, THOSE WHO COVERED THEIR
EYES AND EARS TO SHUT OUT THE
HORROR, THEY NEED TIME, LOVE,
AND PRAYERS.
YOU KNOW, PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID
IT.
PARENTS ARE GOING TO GO HOME,
THEY'RE GOING TO HUG THEIR
CHILDREN, AND EVEN JUST TO
PROCESS THIS AS A NATION, THAT
IS GOING TO TAKE SOME TIME.
>> I THINK ALL OF US ARE TRYING
TO DEAL WITH THIS.
YOU CAN IMAGINE, IF YOU'RE ONE
OF THOSE PARENTS, 20 KIDS
KILLED.
>> THERE IS NOT A PARENT OUT
THERE THAT -- PEOPLE, IT'S NO A
CLICHE, THIS REALLY IS A
PARENT'S WORST NIGHTMARE IS YOU
SEND YOUR KIDS OFF TO SCHOOL AND
YOU THINK THEY'RE GOING TO BE
SAFE AND COME HOME AND THEY
DON'T.
THAT'S HEARTBREAKING, IT REALLY
IS.
>> THANKS VERY MUCH.
CNN'S COVERAGE OF THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTING
CONTINUES.
ERIN BURNETT "OUTFRONT" STARTS
RIGHT NOW.
>>> GOOD EVENING.
BREAKING NEWS.
I'M ASHLEIGH BANFIELD IN FOR
ERIN BURNETT TONIGHT.
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, IT IS
THE SCENE OF ONE OF THE WORST
SCHOOL SHOOTINGS IN THE HISTORY
OF THE UNITED STATES AND WE CAN
REPORT FOR YOU THAT POLICE HAVE
NOW IDENTIFIED A SCHOOL SHOOTER
AS ADAM LANZA.
A SHOOTER WHO KILLED 26 PEOPLE
TODAY AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HERE IN THIS
SMALL CONNECTICUT TOWN.
20 CHILDREN WERE KILLED.
18 OF THEM WERE PRONOUNCED DEAD
RIGHT AT THE SCENE OF THE
SCHOOL.
TWO OF THEM WERE RUSHED TO THE
HOSPITAL, HOPING THAT THEY COULD
SAVE THEM.
THOSE CHILDREN DIED AT THE
HOSPITAL.
SIX ADULTS AT THE SCHOOL WERE
ALSO SHOT DEAD.
AND THEY DIED AT THE SCENE AS
WELL.
NANCY LANZA, A TEACHER AT THE
SCHOOL AND A MOTHER OF THE
SUSPECTED SHOOTER, WAS ALSO
KILLED.
BUT SHE WAS FOUND DEAD IN HER
SON'S HOME IN NEWTOWN.
ADAM LANZA, THE 24-YEAR-OLD
BROTHER RYAN LANZA, WAS TAKEN
INTO POLICE CUSTODY.
RYAN LANZA TAKEN INTO POLICE
CUSTODY FOR QUESTIONING IN
HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY, EARLIER
TODAY.
OFFICIALS HAD NOT LABELED HIM A
SUSPECT.
BUT HE WAS TAKEN AWAY IN
HANDCUFFS.
HIS BROTHER ADAM DIED AT THE
SCENE.
BUT POLICE ARE NOT SAYING AT
THIS POINT IF HE KILLED HIMSELF.
POLICE DID SAY THAT THEY DID NOT
DISCHARGE ANY OF THEIR WEAPONS
AND YET HE WAS DEAD ON THE
SCENE.
LAW ENFORCEMENT SOURCES ALSO
TELLING CNN THAT THE SHOOTER IN
THIS HORRIBLE TRAGEDY WAS
DRESSED IN "BLACK BATTLE
FATIGUES AND A MILITARY VEST."
THE PRINCIPAL OF THIS SCHOOL,
DAWN HUCKSPRUNG, WAS ALSO AMONG
THE DEAD.
A SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST ALSO
KILLED IN THIS SHOOTING RAMPAGE.
IN A MEETING AT THE TIME THE
SHOOTING BEGAN.
THE CHILDREN WERE LED AWAY FROM
THE SCHOOL THIS MORNING SHORTLY
AFTER THE FIRST 911 CALLS CAME
IN THAT BEGAN AT 9:40 THIS
MORNING JUST AFTER SCHOOL HAD
BEGUN.
THOSE SHOOTINGS OCCURRED IN ONE
SECTION OF THE SCHOOL
CONCENTRATED IN ONE AREA,
SPECIFICALLY TWO ROOMS IN AN
AREA OF THE SCHOOL.
AS THE NATION TUNED IN, ONLY TO
SEE DETAIL AFTER DETAIL GET
WORSE, IT IS A NATION IN
MOURNING.
AND TONIGHT THERE IS A VIGIL
OUTSIDE THE WHITE HOUSE.
THE PRESIDENT, PRESIDENT OBAMA,
ORDERING FLAGS TO FLY AT HALF
STAFF NATIONWIDE IN A TRIBUTE TO
THE VICTIMS OF THIS TERRIBLE
TRAGEDY.
AN EXTRAORDINARILY EMOTIONAL
PRESIDENT ADDRESSED THE NATION
THIS AFTERNOON.
>> I KNOW THERE'S NOT A PARENT
IN AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS.
KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
>> Reporter: THE PRESIDENT,
INCREDIBLY EMOTIONAL AS HE
ADDRESSED REPORTERS IN THE
NATION AS THESE HORRIBLE DETAILS
BECAME MORE AND MORE EVIDENT
MOMENT BY MOMENT TODAY.
MY COLLEAGUE SUSAN CANDIOTTI HAS
BEEN WORKING NOT ONLY THE SCENE
OF THE SHOOTING AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY BUT ALSO POLICE
SOURCES THROUGHOUT THIS
COMMUNITY AS WELL.
YOU'VE BEEN ABLE TO FIND OUT
SOME REMARKABLE INFORMATION
THROUGHOUT THE DAY.
>> IT REALLY HAS BEEN STUNNING
THROUGHOUT THE DAY TO TRY TO
FIGURE OUT THE MOTIVE OF THE
SHOOTING AND WE STILL DON'T KNOW
THE ANSWER TO THAT VERY
IMPORTANT QUESTION RIGHT NOW.
AS YOU INDICATED ASHLEIGH, WHAT
WE ARE FINDING OUT IS A LITTLE
BIT ABOUT THE SHOOTER BUT NOT
MUCH.
ONLY THAT HE WAS DRESSED IN
BLACK MILITARY FATIGUES AND THE
A MILITARY-TYPE VEST.
WE ALSO KNOW THAT THEY
DISCOVERED AT LEAST THREE
WEAPONS ON THE SCENE.
TWO HANDGUNS --
>> IN FACT, A GLOCK, A SIG
SAUER, AND A BUSHMASTER 223.
>> EXACTLY.
THE BUSHMASTER 223 IS A
SEMI-AUTOMATIC WEAPON.
WE HAVE PICTURES OF THAT TO SHOW
YOU THE TYPE OF WEAPON.
IT IS NOT THE WEAPON IN
QUESTION, OF COURSE.
WE HAVE YET TO FIND OUT, FOR
EXAMPLE, WHERE THOSE WEAPONS
CAME FROM.
WERE THEY LEGALLY PURCHASED,
WERE THEY STOLEN, TO WHOM WHEN
THEY BRIDGE ADMINISTERED.
>> WE'VE HAD BREAKING NEWS IN
THE LAST WHILE, THAT IN FACT
THOSE WEAPONS, AT LEAST I
BELIEVE TWO OF THEM, WERE
REGISTERED TO THE MOTHER.
NANCY LANZA.
IT'S A VERY DISTRESSING DETAIL.
>> THAT IS INDEED.
>> AT LEAST TWO OF THOSE
WEAPONS, IN FACT, LET ME CHANGE
THAT, AT LEAST THREE OF THE
WEAPONS REG JERRED TO NANCY
LANZA.
>> OF COURSE, HER BODY WAS FOUND
AT A RESIDENCE RIGHT HERE IN THE
AREA.
>> AN ODD DEVELOPMENT.
SUSAN AND I HAVE BEEN TRYING TO
PIECE TOGETHER WHEN THE POLICE
SAID THAT THE SHOOTER KILLED
SOMEONE HE LIVED WITH, AND THEN
WE'VE NOW FOUND OUT THAT NANCY
LANZA WAS FOUND IN HER SON'S
HOME, PUTTING TWO AND TWO
TOGETHER, YOU'D WANT TO COME TO
A CONCLUSION, BUT THEY ARE NOT
RELEASING THAT.
>> IT MAY VERY WELL BE THE
MOTHER'S HOME.
THEY SAY THE SUSPECT'S
RESIDENCE.
WELL, IT MAY BE -- VERY WELL MAY
BE WHERE BOTH OF THEM LIVED
TOGETHER.
SO THAT AGAIN MAKES ONE WONDER,
WHAT PROMPTED ALL OF THIS?
WAS THERE SOMETHING GOING ON?
IT'S HARD NOT TO SPECULATE.
>> THE CONFUSION IS, WELL,
SUSAN, THROUGHOUT THE DAY, THE
NAME RYAN LANZA WAS BEING
REPORTED FAST AND FURIOUSLY.
THIS IS THE BROTHER WHO WAS
TAKEN AWAY IN HANDCUFFS FROM THE
APARTMENT IN HOBOKEN FOR
QUESTIONING.
NOT UNDER ARREST, NOT A SUSPECT.
BUT FOR A LONG TIME, PEOPLE WERE
SUSPECTING THAT RYAN LANZA MIGHT
BE THE SHOOTER.
NOT THE SHOOTER, ACCORDING TO
POLICE.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
THERE WAS CONFLICTING
INFORMATION EVEN AMONG LAW
ENFORCEMENT AUTHORITIES FOR
HOURS NOW.
FINALLY, IT SEEMS TO BE SORTED
OUT, THAT IN FACT IT IS RYAN AS
YOU SAID WHO WAS LED AWAY FOR
QUESTIONING, NOT CONSIDERED A
SUSPECT.
BUT THEY WANTED TO FIND OUT WHAT
THEY COULD ABOUT HIS BROTHER.
>> DO WE KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT
THIS FAMILY?
POLICE HAVE SAID THAT APPARENTLY
ADAM LANZA DID NOT HAVE A
CRIMINAL RECORD, AND YET THIS IS
ONE OF THE MOST HORRIFIC CRIMES
PERPETRATED IN THE MOST HORRIFIC
WAY.
DO WE KNOW ANYTHING ELSE ABOUT
THE FAMILY DYNAMICS?
>> WE HAVE BEEN LEARNING MORE
ABOUT -- A BIT ABOUT THE
BROTHER, ADAM, THE SHOOTER, IN
THIS CASE.
BUT WE ARE STILL TRYING TO GET
THAT CONFIRMED WITH ADDITIONAL
SOURCES BEFORE WE PUT THAT OUT
OFFICIALLY.
BUT WE DO KNOW, FOR EXAMPLE,
THAT THE FATHER OF BOTH OF THEM
WAS DIVORCED FROM NANCY LANZA,
THE SCHOOLTEACHER, AND THE BOYS'
MOTHER.
>> AND DID NOT LIVE AT THIS
RESIDENCE?
>> THE FATHER DID NOT LIVE AT
THIS RESIDENCE, BUT IN FACT HE
HAS REMARRIED AND DOES LIVE IN
THIS AREA OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AS WELL.
SO THEY'VE BEEN TALKING TO HIM,
OBVIOUSLY, AS WELL, TO TRY TO
FIND OUT WHAT INFORMATION, IF
ANY, HE MAY HAVE, WHAT CLUES, IF
ANY, HE MIGHT POSSIBLY HAVE THAT
LED TO THIS.
>> IT'S REMARKABLE THE AMOUNT OF
INFORMATION THAT KEEPS POURS IN.
I'M GOING TO LET YOU WORK YOUR
SOURCES.
I KNOW YOU'VE BEEN ON THE PHONE
HOUR AFTER HOUR.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI DOING A TERRIFIC
JOB.
I WANT TO TAKE YOU TO JASON
CARROLL, MY COLLEAGUE, NOT FAR
AWAY FROM US IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, IN FRONT OF SAINT
ROSE OF LIMA CHURCH.
SET THE SCENE FOR ME.
>> IT'S A VERY SOMBER SCENE AND
SO MANY PEOPLE HERE TRIED TO
COME OUT FOR THIS VIGIL.
YOU CAN SEE BEHIND ME THERE
WASN'T ENOUGH ROOM FOR EVERYONE
INSIDE THE CHURCH.
HUNDREDS PACKED INSIDE, HUNDREDS
MORE OUTSIDE THE CHURCH.
RIGHT NOW, WE'RE TOLD GOVERNOR
MALLOY IS SPEAKING INSIDE THE
CHURCH.
A LITTLE EARLIER TODAY,
ASHLEIGH, I HAD THE OPPORTUNITY
TO SPEAK WITH THE DEACON HERE.
LIKE SO MANY PEOPLE IN THIS
COMMUNITY, HE KNEW SOME OF THE
VICTIMS.
SOME OF THE CHILDREN THAT LOST
THEIR LIVES.
THOSE WERE THE SAME CHILDREN
THAT HE USED TO STARE AT AND SEE
IN THE CHURCH EVERY SUNDAY.
SOME OF THESE CHILDREN HAD THEIR
FIRST COMMUNION HERE.
HE KNEW THE SCHOOL FACULTY,
SERVICE FACULTY CAME TO THIS
CHURCH AS WELL.
DURING A VERY EMOTIONAL MOMENT,
I WANT YOU TO LISTEN TO PART OF
THE CONVERSATION THAT WE HAD A
LITTLE EARLIER ABOUT HOW ALL OF
THIS HAS AFFECTED HIM AND THE
COMMUNITY.
>> IT'S A VERY TIGHT-KNIT
IT'S A VERY LARGE PARISH, A
DYNAMIC PARISH.
EVERYBODY KNOWS EVERYBODY HERE.
AND I DON'T KNOW FOR SURE BUT
I'M SURE THAT QUITE A FEW OF THE
KIDS THAT WE LOST TODAY ARE IN
THIS PARISH.
I HEARD ONE OF THE VICTIMS, I'M
NOT SURE ABOUT IT, BUT I HEARD
THAT ONE OF THE VICTIMS,
RECENTLY SHE -- I THINK IT WAS
BIRTHDAY MONEY, SHE GOT HER
BIRTHDAY MONEY, BIRTHDAY GIFTS.
SHE DONATED IT TO THE PARISH TO
GIVE FOR THE HURRICANE SANDY
VICTIMS.
6 YEARS OLD.
SO THAT'S -- THAT MAKES IT VERY,
VERY PERSONAL.
VERY INTIMATE.
>> Reporter: PERSONAL FOR HIM
AND ALSO PAINFUL, NOT JUST FOR
THE DEACON HERE BUT FOR THE
HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE THAT ARE
PACKED INSIDE THE CHURCH.
AND AGAIN, OUTSIDE THE CHURCH AS
YOU CAN SEE HERE, LISTENING,
TRYING TO FIND SOME SORT OF
COMFORT.
THE DEACON ALSO TOLD ME,
ASHLEIGH, THROUGHOUT THE DAY HE
WAS COUNSELING SOME 100 PEOPLE
WHO HAD COME THROUGH THE CHURCH
DOORS LOOKING FOR ANSWERS, JUST
ASKING QUESTIONS.
THE BIG QUESTION AS YOU CAN
IMAGINE, MOST PEOPLE THAT WERE
COMING IN AND ASKING WAS, WHY?
WHY ALL OF THIS HAPPENED.
AND HE SAID, BECAUSE OF THE
NEWNESS OF IT ALL, HE SAID IT
WAS IMPOSSIBLE TO FIND A WAY TO
SAY SOMETHING PROFOUND.
BUT HE DID REFER TO ONE QUOTE.
HE SAID, WHEN EVERYONE COMES IN
THE AND THEY ASK ME WHY, I PUT
MY ARM AROUND THEM AND I SAY,
ASKING WHY, SOME QUESTIONS ARE
ONLY MEANT FOR GOD TO ANSWER.
LITTLE COMFORT BUT THAT'S ALL
THEY CAN DO AT THIS POINT.
TRYING TO PROVIDE COMFORT AS
EVERYONE HERE TRIES TO GET
THROUGH THIS VERY PAINFUL
MOMENT.
ASHLEIGH?
>> JUST AN EXTRAORDINARY TIME,
AND I CAN'T IMAGINE HOW THEY'RE
GOING TO FIND THAT COMFORT, SO
SOON AFTER THIS HAS HAPPENED.
JASON CARROLL REPORTING FOR US
LIVE JUST ACROSS TOWN FROM WHERE
I AM RIGHT NOW.
THIS HAS BECOME A MULTI-STATE
INVESTIGATION.
POLICE WERE SEARCHING A HOME IN
HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY, EARLIER ON
TODAY.
AND ULTIMATELY TOOK 24-YEAR-OLD
RYAN LANZA IN FOR QUESTIONING.
HE WAS HANDCUFFED AS THEY LED
HIM AWAY.
HE IS BELIEVED TO BE THE BROTHER
OF THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER.
THEY ARE NOT SAYING AT THIS TIME
HE'S A SUSPECT IN ANYTHING, JUST
THAT HE'S WANTED FOR
QUESTIONING.
MY COLLEAGUE JOHN BERMAN IS LIVE
IN HOBOKEN.
TELL ME EXACTLY WHAT THE POLICE
THINK ANY CONNECTION MIGHT AND
BE WHY HE WOULD HAVE BEEN
HANDCUFFED, JOHN.
>> Reporter: OH, YOU KNOW
ASHLEIGH, AT THIS POINT WE
SIMPLY DON'T KNOW.
AS YOU SAY THIS HAS BEEN THE
SITE OF AN ENORMOUS AMOUNT OF
ACTIVITY, AN ENORMOUS AMOUNT OF
QUESTIONS, NOW AN ENORMOUS
AMOUNT OF CONFUSION, REALLY.
YOU TALKED ABOUT THAT PICTURE WE
SAW EARLIER OF RYAN LANZA BEING
LED FROM THIS APARTMENT IN
HANDCUFFS.
HE WAS TAKING IN FOR
QUESTIONING.
ALSO CNN HAS LEARNED, TAKEN IN
FOR QUESTIONING TWO ROOMMATES
APPARENTLY OF RYAN LANZA,
BROUGHT IN FOR QUESTIONING, NOT
BELIEVED TO BE CONNECTED IN ANY
WAY TO THE SUSPECT ADAM LANZA.
THE HOBOKEN POLICE WERE HERE,
JERSEY CITY POLICE WERE HERE,
THERE WAS A BOMB SQUAD HERE, FBI
WERE HERE, THE FBI ACTUALLY
REMOVED SOME MATERIALS FROM THIS
APARTMENT, INCLUDING PERHAPS A
COMPUTER.
BUT AT THIS POINT, IT IS NOW
CLEAR THAT THE SHOOTER WAS NOT
RYAN LANZA, IT WAS HIS BROTHER
ADAM LANZA.
RYAN WE BELIEVE IS STILL IN
CUSTODY.
I CAN TELL YOU, THIS ASHLEIGH.
WHILE THE SCENE WAS BUZZING WITH
ALL THOSE LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS IT IS MUCH, MUCH
QUIETER NOW.
THIS STREET HAD BEEN CLOSED
DOWN, NOW IT'S WIDE OPEN.
JUST A FEW TOKEN POLICE STANDING
OUTSIDE THE APARTMENT BUILDING
WHERE RYAN LANZA LIVES.
IT'S A FIVE-STORY APARTMENT
BUILDING.
TWO AND THREE BEDROOM
APARTMENTS.
HOBOKEN, IT'S A HIP CITY RIGHT
NOW, A LOT OF PEOPLE, YOUNG
FAMILIES HERE, YOUNG PEOPLE LIVE
HERE, OFTEN WORK IN NEW YORK
CITY.
RYAN LANZA, 24, WE DON'T KNOW A
WHOLE LOT ABOUT HIM.
WE BELIEVE HE'S IS CUSTODY BUT
NOT, NOT APPARENTLY THE SHOOTER
AS HAD BEEN REPORTED FOR A LONG
TIME TODAY.
ASHLEY?
>> IT WILL BE DEVASTATING FOR
THAT FAMILY UNDOUBTEDLY.
JOHN BERMAN LIVE IN HOE BOKE 10
FOR US.
OBVIOUSLY AS THIS STARTED TO
TRANSPIRE ALARM BELLS WENT OFF
THROUGHOUT THE DISTRICT HERE.
THE ENTIRE SCHOOL DISTRICT WENT
INTO LOCKDOWN.
THE REACTION WAS SWIFT AND THE
ACTIONS OF TEACHERS THROUGHOUT
THIS DISTRICT WERE SERIOUS.
RENEE BURN IS ONE OF THESE
TEACHERS, SHE'S A KINDERGARTEN
TEACHERS' AIDE, HOLLY ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, AND SHE KNEW SOME OF THE
TEACHERS AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY AS WELL.
HER SCHOOL WAS IN LOCKDOWN A
COUPLE OF HOURS FOLLOWING THE
SHOOTING.
RENEE, THANK YOU FOR TALKING TO
US.
TAKE ME INSIDE YOUR SCHOOL AND
TELL ME HOW THIS DAY UNFOLDED
FOR YOU AND WHEN YOU ULTIMATELY
FOUND OUT WHY YOU WERE IN
LOCKDOWN.
>> IT STARTED OUT AS A NORMAL
DAY.
WE HAD OUR HOL LAY PARTY
SCHEDULED FOR OUR KINDERGARTEN
CLASS WHICH WAS SCHEDULED TO
START ABOUT 10:15.
AND ABOUT 9:45, WE HEARD THE
ANNOUNCEMENT THAT WE WERE IN
LO
LOCKDOWN.
>> DID YOU THINK THIS WOULD BE A
DRILL?
>> I KNEW IT WASN'T A DRILL
BECAUSE WE HAD ABOUT 60 PARENTS
SCHEDULED TO COME INTO THE
SCHOOL FOR OUR CELEBRATION.
AND I KNEW THERE WAS SOMETHING
GOING ON.
BUT NEVER, NEVER THOUGHT IT WAS
ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
THE LAST TIME WE WENT INTO A
LOCKDOWN WAS BECAUSE THERE WAS
SOMETHING TO DO WITH A BANK
HOLDUP IN TOWN AND JUST AS A
MATTER OF COURSE THEY SHUT DOWN
THE SCHOOLS.
>> WHEN THIS HAPPENED, WHAT DID
YOU DO RIGHT AWAY?
>> WE KEPT ALL THE KIDS CALM AND
QUIET AND WE CLOSED OUR DOORS
AND WE WERE ABLE TO MOVE ABOUT
WITHIN THE SCHOOL.
BUT NO ONE WAS TOO GO IN OR OUT.
>> WERE YOU GETTING ANY TEXT
MESSAGES OR E-MAILS FROM FAMILY
OR FRIENDS?
>> IT STARTED ALMOST
IMMEDIATELY.
PEOPLE WANT TUESDAY KNOW WHAT
WAS HAPPEN IS.
WE HAD NO INFORMATION.
WE COULDN'T GO ON THE INTERNET,
WE COULDN'T TAKE PHONE CALLS.
>> YOU WEREN'T ALLOWED TO TAKE
PHONE CALLS AT THIS TIME?
>> WE WERE TAKING OUR CELL PHONE
CALLS BUT NO REGULAR PHONE CALLS
WERE COMING IN AND OUT OF THE
SCHOOL.
I KNEW SOMETHING WAS UP WHEN MY
SON CALLED ME FROM NEW YORK AND
WANTED TO KNOW WHAT WAS GOING
ON.
AT THAT POINT, WE HAD NO
INFORMATION.
>> THIS IS A SMALL COMMUNITY.
AND YOU KNEW SOME OF THE
TEACHERS OR YOU CERTAIN LLY DO
KNOW SOME OF THE TEACHERS AT
SANDY HOOK.
>> ALL THE TEACHERS.
IT'S SUCH A SMALL COMMUNITY, WE
KNOW ALL THE TEACHERS.
ONE OF OUR TEACHERS HAD A
DAUGHTER IN KINDERGARTEN AT
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL SO WE WERE
FRANTIC.
>> THAT IS CHILD ACCOUNTED FOR?
>> SHE'S OKAY.
THANK GOD SHE'S OKAY BUT WE
DIDN'T KNOW THAT FOR QUITE A
WHILE.
>> FOR HOW LONG WAS SHE UNAWARE
AND COULDN'T LEAVE THE SCHOOL?
>> HE COULDN'T LEAVE THE SCHOOL
AND HE COULDN'T CALL THE SCHOOL
AND WE HAD NO INFORMATION.
IT WAS A GOOD TWO HOURS INTO IT.
>> THE PRINCIPAL OF SANDY HOOK,
DAWN HOCKSFROM, DID YOU KNOW
HER?
>> I DIDN'T KNOW HER PERSONALLY,
SHELVES NEW THIS YEAR, BUT I
UNDERSTAND SHE HAS FIVE CHILDREN
IN THE SCHOOL SYSTEM.
>> SHE HAS FIVE CHILDREN?
DID YOU KNOW ANY OF THE OTHER
TEACHERS OR HAVE YOU BEEN TOLD
OF ANY OTHER IDENTITIES?
ARE YOU WAITING LIKE EVERYONE
ELSE?
>> WE DON'T KNOW WHAT THE
IDENTITY OF THE VICTIMS WERE,
ONLY THE ONE TEACHER.
>> AND SINCE -- AS I UNDERSTAND
IT, ABOUT 27,000 PEOPLE LIVE IN
THIS COMMUNITY?
YOU HAVE TO HAVE KNOWN PEOPLE
WHO HAVE BEEN DIRECTLY AFFECTED.
HAVE YOU BEEN ABLE TO ASCERTAIN
WHICH PARENTS HAVE NOT BEEN
REUNITED WITH THEIR CHILDREN
YET?
>> WE -- NO, NOT YET.
IT'S ALL UNKNOWN TOWELS RIGHT
NOW.
LIKE I SAID, THE ONLY ONE WE DO
KNOW FOR CERTAIN IS THAT OUR
TEACHER, OUR FOURTH GRADE
TEACHER, KNOWS THAT HIS DAUGHTER
IS SAFE TODAY.
>> AND JUST IF YOU COULD, KEVIN,
JUST ASSESS FOR ME HOW IS THIS
TOWN REACTING SO EARLY AFTER
THIS INCIDENT?
HOW ARE YOU PROCESSING THIS?
WHAT KIND OF INFORMATION ARE YOU
GETTING FROM YOUR OFFICIALS AND
WHAT ARE YOUR NEIGHBORS SAYING?
>> I THINK IT'S JUST A STATE OF
SHOCK.
IT REALLY IS A -- THE TRAGEDY, I
MEAN, IT REALLY IS AS INTENSE AS
ONE COULD IMAGINE IT TO BE THAT
IT SEEMS LIKE A ROYAL CHANGE
TODAY.
>> YOUR GOVERNOR, DAN MALLOY,
SAID TODAY THAT HE WAS A MAYOR
IN STANFORD CONNECTICUT ON 9/11.
HE SAYS HE NEVER THOUGHT THIS
KIND OF EVIL WOULD BE VISITED
UPON HIM IN HIS OFFICE IN THIS
STATE AGAIN.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I AM SO SORRY FOR THE LOSSES
THAT YOU'RE GOING TO BE FEELING
FOR SO LONG.
>> SOMETHING LIKE THIS DOES NOT
HAPPEN IN NEWTOWN.
IT'S SUCH A SMALL TOWN AND A
CLOSE TOWN.
JUST -- I CAN'T GET MY HEAD
WRAPPED AROUND THIS.
>> RENEE AND KEVIN BURN, THANK
YOU, I APPRECIATE YOUR TIME.
THANK YOU, GOD BLESS.
WE HAVE A LOT MORE AHEAD AS WE
CONTINUE TO GET OUR COVERAGE IN,
AS DETAILS CONTINUE TO COME IN
AS WELL.
YOU'RE GOING TO HEAR FROM A
TEACHER INSIDE THE SCHOOL WHO IS
RIGHT NOW BEING CALLED A HERO
FOR SAVING A STUDENT.
IT'S ALL COMING UP IN A MOMENT.
>> THIS EVENING, MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT
IN AMERICA WILL DO, WHICH IS HUG
OUR CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER
AND WE'LL TELL THEM THAT WE LOVE
THEM.
AND WE'LL REMIND EACH OTHER HOW
DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT.
AND THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT
NOW.
IN THE HARD DAYS TO COME, THAT
COMMUNITY NEEDS US TO BE AT OUR
BEST AS AMERICANS AND I WILL DO
EVERYTHING IN MY POWER AS
PRESIDENT TO HELP.
WITH THE ABILITY TO IMPROVE
ROI THROUGH SEO
ALL BY COB.
AND YOU...RENT FROM NATIONAL.
BECAUSE ONLY NATIONAL LETS YOU
CHOOSE ANY CAR IN THE AISLE...
AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE
A FULL-SIZE OR ABOVE,
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
I'M GOING B-I-G.
[ Male Announcer ] GOOD CHOICE
BUSINESS PRO. GOOD CHOICE.
GO NATIONAL.
GO LIKE A PRO.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS KAREN AND JEREMIAH.
THEY DON'T KNOW IT YET,
BUT THEY'RE GONNA FALL IN LOVE,
GET MARRIED,
HAVE A COUPLE OF KIDS,
[ children laughing ]
MOVE TO THE COUNTRY,
AND LIVE A LONG, HAPPY LIFE
TOGETHER
WHERE THEY ALMOST NEVER FIGHT
ABOUT MONEY.
[ dog barks ]
BECAUSE RIGHT AFTER
THEY GET MARRIED,
THEY'LL FIND
SOME RETIREMENT PEOPLE
WHO ARE PAID ON SALARY,
NOT COMMISSION.
THEY'LL GET
STRAIGHTFORWARD GUIDANCE
AND BE ABLE TO FOCUS ON OTHER
THINGS, LIKE EACH OTHER,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
>>> THE SCENE TONIGHT AT THE
WASHINGTON MONUMENT IN OUR
NATION'S CAPITAL AS PEOPLE
GATHER TO REMEMBER THOSE PEOPLE
WHO ARE SO SADLY SLAUGHTERED
HERE IN CONNECTICUT TODAY.
CHILDREN, 20 CHILDREN IN AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
SIX OF THE TEACHERS IN THE
A NATION IN MOURNING,
CONNECTICUT LEGISLATORS AMONG
THOSE AT THAT CANDLELIGHT VIGIL
AT THE WASHINGTON MONUMENT.
ONE OF THE PEOPLE WHO WITHOUT
QUESTION IT BEARS TO NOTE IS
CAITLIN LLOYD.
SHE'S A FIRST GRADE TEACHER AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
TONIGHT SHE IS BEING CALLED A
HERO BECAUSE SHE SAVED SOME OF
THE STUDENTS WHEN THE GUNFIRE
BEGAN TO ERUPT.
EARLIER, SHE SPOKE WITH ABC'S
"WORLD NEWS TONIGHT."
>> I PUT ONE OF MY STUDENTS ON
TOP OF THE TOILET.
I KNEW WE HAD TO GET IN THERE.
I WAS TELLING THEM, IT'S GOING
TO BE OKAY, YOU'RE GOING TO BE
ALL RIGHT.
I HAD PULLED A BOOKSHELF BEFORE
I CLOSED THE DOOR IN FRONT OF IT
SO IT WAS COMPLETELY -- WE WERE
COMPLETELY BARRICADED IN, I
TURNED THE LIGHTS OFF.
>> DID YOU TELL THEM TO BE
QUIET?
>> OH, YES, I TOLD THEM TO BE
QUIET.
I TOLD THEM WE HAD TO BE
ABSOLUTELY QUIET.
BECAUSE I WAS SO AFRAID IF HE
DID COME IN, HE WOULD HEAR US,
MAYBE HE WOULD START SHOOTING
THE DOOR.
I SAID, WE HAVE TO BE ABSOLUTELY
QUIET.
I SAID, THERE ARE BAD GUYS OUT
THERE NOW, WE HAVE TO WAIT FOR
THE GOOD GUYS.
>> THE EMOTION IS SO PALPABLE.
WITH EVERY STORY THAT BEGINS TO
EMERGE FROM WHAT HAPPENED, ONE
OF THE STORIES THAT EMERGED WAS
THAT THE TEACHERS TOLD THE
CHILDREN AS THIS CALAMITY WAS
UNFOLDING NOT TO WORRY, THAT
THOSE SOUNDS THEY WERE HEARING
WAS JUST A WILD ANIMAL THAT HAD
GOTTEN INTO THE SCHOOL AND THEY
WERE CLOSING THE DOORS TO MAKE
SURE THAT ANIMAL COULDN'T GET
INTO THEIR CLASSROOMS SO A LOT
OF THOSE CHILDREN WERE SHIELDED.
ANOTHER STORY OF A CHILD TELLING
A LOCAL REPORTER AS THEY WERE
BEING LED OUT OF THE SCHOOL,
THEY WERE ASKED TO AVERT THEIR
EYES AS THEY WALKED PAST ONE OF
THE AREAS.
THIS IS A VERY SMALL COMMUNITY.
IT IS WITHOUT QUESTION THE STORY
YOU HEAR OVER AND OVER IN THESE
SHOOTINGS, A PLACE THAT HAS
27,000 PEOPLE.
IT'S JUST NOT THE KIND OF PLACE
YOU WOULD EXPECT A HORROR LIKE
THIS TO VISIT.
IT'S ABOUT 80 MILES NORTHEAST OF
NEW YORK CITY.
THE SCHOOL IS IN A WOODED
RESIDENTIAL AREA.
IT IS PEACEFUL.
IT IS BEAUTIFUL.
IT IS SAFE IN THIS COMMUNITY.
THE SCHOOLS ARE EXCELLENT.
AND OVER THE PAST DECADE, THERE
HAS BEEN ONLY ONE MURDER.
IN ONE DECADE.
POLICE LIEUTENANT SAID, THIS IS
THE MOST TRAGIC THING WE'VE EVER
ENCOUNTERED.
OUT FRONT TONIGHT IS DAVID OWENS
WITH "THE HARTFORD CURRENT"
COVERING THESE DETAILS AS
THEY'VE UNFOLDED.
GET ME UP TO SPEED ON THE LATEST
INFORMATION YOU'VE BEEN ABLE TO
GLEAN AS WE'VE BEEN TRYING TO
PIECE TOGETHER THIS HORRIBLE
PUZZLE.
>> THE LATEST IS POLICE ARE
IDENTIFYING A YOUNG MAN AS THE
SHOOTER AND THERE ARE VICTIMS
ELSEWHERE OTHER THAN THE SCHOOL
HERE.
AND POLICE ARE TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT WHAT THE HECK HAPPENED.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER IS SETTING
UP A TEMPORARY MORGUE NEAR THE
SCHOOL WHERE THEY'RE GOING TO
WORK TO IDENTIFY THE VICTIMS.
MAKE MOTIVATIONNOTIFICATIONS, H
IDENTIFIED BY THE FAMILIES,
BEGIN THE LONG PROCESS.
>> THE MANPOWER THAT IT IS GOING
TO REQUIRE TO PROCESS THIS
FORENSIC SCENE, TO DO POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATION MATCHES WITH EACH
OF THESE BODIES, I CAN'T IMAGINE
THAT A TOWN THIS SMALL COULD
HAVE DONE THIS.
THEY HAVE HAD SO MANY
COMMUNITIES COME IN TO HELP.
>> THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
VERY TYPICALLY JOIN IN IN
INVESTIGATIONS LIKE THIS, AWFUL,
LARGE-SCALE INCIDENTS.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER HAVE
BROUGHT STAFF DOWN HERE.
EVERYTHING IS ON-SITE AND
THEY'RE WORKING HERE AS
EXPEDITIOUSLY AS POSSIBLE TO
BEGIN TO HELP THESE FAMILIES GET
THE INFORMATION THEY NEED TO
COME FORWARD.
>> SOMETIMES WHEN THESE STORIES
BREAK, LIVING IN A LARGE
COMMUNITY LIKE HARTFORD,
CERTAINLY NEW YORK, STANFORD,
ANY OF THESE SURROUNDING
COMMUNITIES, YOU HEAR THE REPORT
OF SHOTS FIRED OR SOME KIND OF
VIOLENCE BEING PERPETRATED AND
IT MIGHT NOT BE SUCH A SURPRISE.
THEN YOU HEAR ABOUT THIS TOWN.
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WHAT WAS YOUR FIRST REACTION IN
YOUR NEWSROOM?
>> I WASN'T IN THE NEWSROOM.
I GOT A CALL FROM A FRIEND WHO
SAID, THERE'S A REPORT OF SHOTS
FIRED AT A SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
AND I STARTED HEADING HERE,
CONTACTED MY BOSS.
HE SAID, GET DOWN THERE.
>> WERE YOU FAMILIAR WITH
NEWTOWN?
BEEN HERE BEFORE, IT'S A VERY
NICE COMMUNITY, A SAFE COMMUNITY
JUST AS YOU DESCRIBED.
A VERY NICE PLACE TO LIVE.
>> AGAIN, JUST TO HEAR THE
STATISTIC, ONE MURDER IN TEN
YEARS, THIS HAD TO BE
ASTOUNDING.
>> YES.
>> DID YOU HAVE ANY IDEA THE
MAGNITUDE OF WHAT'S GOING TO
UNFOLD?
>> I DIDN'T.
AS INFORMATION BEGAN TO COME
OUT, IT BECAME CLEAR THAT IT WAS
GOING TO BE AWFUL.
IT'S AWFUL BEYOND COMPREHENSION.
>> THE ATF IS HERE, THE FBI IS
HERE, THE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE, OBVIOUSLY THE LOCAL
POLICE AS WELL.
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA ABOUT
ADDITIONAL MANPOWER THAT MAY BE
HEADED THIS WAY?
>> THERE'S ALL KINDS OF
AGENCIES.
I BELIEVE THE MARSHALS ARE HERE.
THE U.S. ATTORNEY'S OFFICE IS
PROVIDING SUPPORT.
IT'S PRIMARILY GOING TO BE A
STATE POLICE CASE WITH
HIGH-TRAINED MAJOR CRIME SQUADS
THAT WILL DO THE FORENSIC
INVESTIGATION IN THE SCHOOL AND
THE DETECTIVES, WORKING WITH THE
NEWTOWN DETECTIVES, FIGURING OUT
WHAT HAPPENED HERE AND WHY.
>> OF COURSE, THERE IS THIS
SECONDARY CRIME SCENE.
THE RESIDENTS.
>> YES.
>> WHERE THE MOTHER WAS
DISCOVERED IN THE RESIDENCE OF
HER SON.
WE'RE NOT CLEAR AS TO WHETHER
THE MONEY AND THE SON, THAN
CONTRACT LANZA, THE MOTHER, ADAM
LANZA, WHETHER THEY LIVED
TOGETHER.
DO YOU KNOW ANYTHING ELSE ABOUT
THIS FAMILY, THE LANZA FAMILY?
>> I DON'T.
MY UNDERSTANDING IS SHE WAS A
TEACHER.
BUT I DON'T HAVE A LOT OF
DETAIL.
MY COLLEAGUES BACK IN HARTFORD
ARE WORKING ON THAT KIND OF
INFORMATION.
>> AND THEN THERE WAS THIS -- A
DIVORCE, A FATHER WHO LIVED IN A
DIFFERENT PART OF THE COMMUNITY
BUT CERTAINLY IN THIS AREA.
IS THERE ANY KNOWLEDGE ABOUT HIS
WHEREABOUTS AND WHETHER HE WAS
ABLE TO HELP IN THIS
INVESTIGATION?
>> HE LIVED IN A COMMUNITY NEAR
NEWTOWN IN FAIRFIELD COUNTY.
>> SO FAR, NO INFORMATION ON
WHETHER POLICE HAVE BEEN ABLE TO
INTERVIEW HIM, TALK TO HIM?
>> POLICE HAVE TALKED TO
EVERYBODY IN THE FAMILY.
FROM WHAT I UNDERSTAND.
>> AND THEN JUST, IF YOU WOULD,
DAVID, MAYBE JUST TAKE ME TO THE
SCENE OF THE FIREHOUSE WHERE AS
THIS EMERGENCY WAS UNFOLDING,
THE TEACHERS WHO HAD THE
WHEREWITHAL TO GET THOSE
CHILDREN OUT, EVACUATE THE ONES
THEY COULD, THEY RAN.
THEY PHYSICALLY RAN THE DISTANCE
BETWEEN THE SCHOOL AND THE
FIREHOUSE FOR SHELTER, RIGHT?
>> THE POLICE WERE AT THE SCHOOL
VERY QUICKLY.
THEY WENT RIGHT IN.
AND THE TEACHERS AS YOU
DESCRIBED HAD LOCKED THE DOORS.
THE POLICE STARTED ESCORTING THE
KIDS OUT.
THEY SAID, HOLD HANDS AND CLOSE
YOUR EYES.
AND THE KIDS --
>> THE POLICE TOLD THE CHILDREN,
HOLD HANDS AND CLOSE YOUR EYES.
THIS SQUARES WITH WHAT ONE OF
THE CHILDREN HAD TOLD THE LOCAL
REPORTER, THEY HAD BEEN ASKED TO
AVERT THEIR EYES AS THEY WENT
PAST THIS AREA.
>> THEY OPENED THEIR EYES WHEN
THEY GOT OUTSIDE, THEY WERE
HUSTLED OVER TO THE FIREHOUSE
WHERE THEY WERE ENVELOPED AND
TAKEN CARE OF AND PARENTS BEGAN
TO ARRIVE.
PANICKED PARENTS.
AS TRAUMATIC AND AS PANICKY AS
THIS MAY HAVE BEEN, IT WAS
REMARKABLY CALM AS PARENTS
ARRIVED.
>> AMAZING.
>> TO CHECK, TO PICK UP THEIR
CHILDREN.
>> STAND BY IF YOU WILL, I JUST
WANT TO MAKE A NOTE WE'RE
GETTING SOME VIDEO BEING FED IN
TO US LIVE RIGHT NOW.
JUST ACROSS TOWN TRANSFER TWO
VIGILS THAT HAVE BEEN TAKING
PLACE.
DAN MAY DO I, THE GOVERNOR, IS
SPEAKING AT ONE OF THEM.
>> IN THE COMING DAYS AS MANY OF
US PREPARE TO CELEBRATE THE
BIRTH OF CHRIST, UNDERSTAND THAT
THAT TOO WILL BRING SORROW AS WE
THINK ABOUT THESE INSTANCES THAT
HAVE HAPPENED SO CLOSE TO THOSE
DAYS.
THAT TOO WILL PASS AND BE
OVERCOME.
AND ALL OF OUR PRAYERS AND THE
PRAYERS AND HOPES OF THE PUBLIC
OFFICIALS WHO HAVE ASSEMBLED
HERE TODAY AND IN THE PRESENCE
OF YOUR GREAT SELECTORS, I BRING
AND EXTEND THE CONDOLENCES OF
THE ENTIRETY OF THIS STATE TO
YOU, THE MEMBERS OF THIS
COMMUNITY.
MAY GOD BLESS YOU.
MAY GOD BLESS OUR CHILDREN WHO
ARE WITH US TODAY AND THOSE WHO
WERE TAKEN AWAY AND MAY GOD
BLESS THE ADULTS WHO LOST THEIR
LIVES TODAY.
THANK YOU.
>> DAVID OWENS IS A REPORTER FOR
"THE HARTFORD CURRENT."
HE'S STILL WITH ME.
I WANT TO ASK YOU ABOUT THE
GOVERNOR.
DAN MALLOY HAS BEEN HERE TO
UPDATE US ON SOME OF THE
INFORMATION, AS WELL AS THE
LIEUTENANT WITH THE STATE POLICE
WHO HAS BEEN VERY HELPFUL.
THERE'S SOMETHING THAT WAS SAID
EARLIER THAT STOOD OUT TO ME.
THAT IS, WHEN ALL OF THOSE
PARENTS CONGREGATED AT THE FIRE
STATION, MANY OF THEM WERE
REUNITED WITH CHILDREN.
AS THE CHILDREN WERE FOUND AND
BROUGHT OVER, BUT THERE WAS ONE
POINT WHERE THE GOVERNOR
ACTUALLY SAID TO THE PARENTS,
ANYONE WHO HASN'T BEEN REUNITED
WITH YOUR CHILDREN, YOU WILL NOT
BE.
THIS MUST HAVE BEEN ONE OF THE
MOST DIFFICULT TIMES.
>> I CAN'T IMAGINE IT FOR
ANYBODY.
IT'S JUST A PARENT'S NIGHTMARE.
10-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER, I CAN'T
IMAGINE WHAT THOSE PEOPLE ARE
GOING THROUGH.
>> AND I WANT TO JUST HEAD BACK
INTO THIS VIGIL FOR A MOMENT AND
LISTEN IN.
>> -- ALL OF YOUR EMOTION.
AND YOU ARE SENDING A MESSAGE TO
ALL OF AMERICA.
AND BELIEVE ME, THE HEARTS AND
PRAYERS OF AMERICA ARE WITH YOU
TONIGHT.
THANK YOU FOR BEING HERE.
AND THANK YOU FOR BRINGING YOUR
CHILDREN.
SO THAT THEY CAN SEE THAT THERE
IS GOOD IN PEOPLE.
AND THANK YOU FOR REAFFIRMING,
ESPECIALLY AT THIS SEASON, FOR
ALL OF US, WHATEVER OUR FAITH,
WHATEVER OUR BELIEFS ON OTHER
OCCASIONS ON OTHER ISSUES, THAT
WE ARE ONE PEOPLE AND WE WILL BE
ONE PEOPLE IN TIMES OF CRISIS
AND TESTING AND ADVERSITY.
I THANK YOU.
>> SENATOR RICHARD PLUBLUMENTHA
THE U.S. DEMOCRAT, GIVING
REGULAR UPDATES, STAND UNTIL
SOLIDARITY WITH THE LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICERS AND
GOVERNOR DAN MALLOY, WHO HAS
ALSO BEEN GIVING REGULAR UPDATES
TO THE MEDIA AND HAS BEEN
MEETING PERSONALLY WITH THESE
FAMILIES, PARTICULARLY THE MOST
POIGNANT MOMENT I HEARD OF
TODAY.
THAT WAS THE GOVERNOR OF THIS
STATE ADDRESSING THESE FAMILIES
AND FOR THE FIRST TIME LETTING
THESE FAMILIES KNOW ANYONE WHO
HAS NOT BEEN REUNITED WITH YOUR
CHILDREN, AT THIS POINT THERE
WILL BE NO MORE CHILDREN
REUNITED WITH FAMILIES.
IT HAD TO BE SAID THIS WAY I CAN
ONLY IMAGINE BECAUSE THOSE
POSITIVE IDENTIFICATIONS HAVE
NOT BEEN MADE.
THIS IS AN OVERWHELMING FORENSIC
TASK THAT IS GOING ON AS WE
SPEAK IN THE SCHOOLS.
IN THE SCHOOL.
IF YOU CAN IMAGINE FOR A MOMENT
THE TEAMS THAT ARE GOING INTO
THAT SCHOOL TO IDENTIFY EVERY
ONE OF THOSE 18 LITTLE BODIES.
18 OF THOSE CHILDREN DIED WHERE
THEY WERE IN THAT SCHOOL.
THEIR BODIES REMAIN THERE.
TWO ADDITIONAL CHILDREN WERE
RACED TO THE HOSPITAL.
THEY WERE HOPING THEY COULD SAVE
THEM BUT THEY DIED IN THE
HOSPITAL.
SIX OF THE ADULTS WERE ALSO
KILLED ON THE SCENE.
AND EVERY SINGLE ONE OF THESE 20
PEOPLE MUST BE IDENTIFIED.
THAT IS A MAMMOTH TASK AND THE
GOVERNOR WAS TRYING TO DO WHAT
HE COULD TO AT LEAST GIVE
WHATEVER INFORMATION HE POSSIBLY
COULD DO THESE FAMILIES.
LET'S GO BACK AND TAKE A LOOK AT
SOME OF THESE LIVE SCENES IN THE
VIGIL THAT'S JUST ACROSS TOWN.
MY COLLEAGUE JASON CARROLL IS
STANDING BY OUTSIDE OF THE
VIGIL.
JASON, I'M HAVING TROUBLE
HEARING BUT IF YOU COULD SET THE
SCENE FOR ME THERE AND LET ME
KNOW WHO HAS ATTENDED, WHO
SHOWED UP FOR TONIGHT'S VISIBLE
JILL WHERE YOU ARE?
>> Reporter: THOUSANDS TRIED TO
OR SHOWED UP HERE AT THE CHURCH
AT ST. ROSE LIMA CHURCH.
AT LEAST 500 PEOPLE PACKED
INSIDE.
MORE OUTSIDE, IF YOU LOOK BEHIND
ME, THERE ARE SEVERAL HUNDRED
PEOPLE STANDING OUTSIDE IN THE
FREEZING COLD.
SIMPLY NOT ENOUGH ROOM FOR
EVERYONE INSIDE THE CHURCH
TONIGHT, ASHLEIGH.
THE REASON FOR THAT IS SIMPLY
BECAUSE THIS IS A COMMUNITY, YOU
HEARD IT OVER AND OVER AGAIN,
THIS IS A COMMUNITY THAT IS A
CLOSE COMMUNITY.
A NUMBER OF PEOPLE HERE KNEW
EACH OTHER.
WHEN THE WORD STARTED TO SPREAD
THERE WAS GOING TO BE A VIGIL
HERE TONIGHT, EVERYONE CAME OUT.
EVERYONE LOOKING FOR COMFORT.
EVERYONE GRIEVING HERE IN THIS
COMMUNITY.
EVEN IF YOU DIDN'T PERSONALLY
LOSE SOMEONE, THE FEELING OF
LOSS IS STILL THERE FOR SO MANY
PEOPLE HERE.
WE'RE HEARING MORE TONIGHT ABOUT
THE PRINCIPAL OF THIS SCHOOL AS
WELL.
DAWN LAFFERTY HOCKSBRAWN.
47 YEARS OLD.
BY ALL ACCOUNTS LOVED THE SCHOOL
SHE HAD WORKED AT SINCE JUNE
2010.
HERE'S WHAT'S INTERESTING.
SHE HAD RECENTLY INSTALLED A NEW
SECURITY SYSTEM AT THE SCHOOL
WHERE VISITORS ACTUALLY HAD TO
BE THE BUZZED TO BE LET IN.
THIS WAS A SCHOOL, SHE WAS KNOWN
AS A TOUGH LADY, THIS WAS A
SCHOOL SHE CARED DEEPLY, DEEPLY
ABOUT.
AND SHE HAD ALSO MAINTAINED A
VERY ACTIVE TWITTER ACCOUNT.
IN FACT, JUST ON DECEMBER 12th,
I SAW ONE OF THE TWEETS SHE HAD
WRITTEN.
IT SAID, SANDY HOOK STUDENTS,
ENJOY THE REHEARSAL FOR OUR
FOURTH GRADE WINTER CONCERT.
THAT'S JUST ONE OF THE TWEETS
SHE HAD JUST SENT OUT ON
WEDNESDAY.
AND AS I WAS SAYING A LITTLE
EARLIER, SO MANY PEOPLE WHO CAME
OUT HERE TONIGHT, EVEN IF THEY
DIDN'T LOSE ANYONE PERSONALLY,
MOST LIKELY THEY KNEW SOMEONE AT
THE SCHOOL.
IN FACT, ONE OF THOSE WHO CAME
OUT HERE TONIGHT, A AN THAT WE
SPOKE TO OUT HERE, KNEW THE
PRINCIPAL.
HE TALKED ABOUT HER.
I JUST WANT YOU TO LISTEN TO
WHAT HE HAD TO SAY BEFORE HE
HEADED INSIDE INTO THE VIGIL.
>> JASON, I'M HAVING TROUBLE
CATCHING YOU.
I THINK I'VE LOST YOUR AUDIO.
I WANT TO JUST RESET THE SCENE
FOR ANYONE JOINING US.
JASON CARROLL HAS BEEN ACROSS
TOWN AT A VIGIL THAT BEGAN AT
7:00 TONIGHT FOR THOSE WHO WERE
LOST AT NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, AT
THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, A SCHOOL THAT HAS
STUDENTS FROM KIND GAR 10
THROUGH FOURTH GRADE.
IT IS A SCHOOL THAT HAS LOST 20,
20 OF ITS STUDENTS.
IN JUST A MATTER OF MINUTES.
18 OF THEM DYING WHERE THEY
WERE, TWO OF THEM BEING RUSHED
TO THE HOSPITAL, DYING AT THE
HOSPITAL.
SIX OF THE ADULTS IN THE SCHOOL
ALSO KILLED.
THIS HAS BEEN AN UNBELIEVABLE
DAY HERE IN THIS SLEEPY
CONNECTICUT TOWN.
POLICE ARE NOW IDENTIFYING THE
SHOOTER AS ADAM LANZA.
IT TOOK A LONG TIME FOR AN
IDENTIFICATION BECAUSE HE ALSO
HAS A BROTHER AND HIS BROTHER IS
IN HOBOKEN, NAMED RYAN LANZA.
HE WAS TAKEN AWAY IN HANDCUFFS
FROM HIS APARTMENT IN HOBOKEN
FOR QUESTIONING BUT THEY ARE NOT
SAYING HE'S A SUSPECT AT THIS
TIME.
WE DO KNOW THAT NANCY LANZA, THE
MOTHER OF THESE TWO YOUNG MEN,
WAS KILLED TODAY AND THAT SHE
WAS A TEACHER AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
TOM FOREMAN HAS BEEN PIECING
TOGETHER HOW THIS TERRIBLE CRIME
UNFOLDED FROM THE MOMENT THE
FIRST FEW PHONE CALLS STARTED
COMING IN JUST AFTER 9:30 IN THE
MORNING.
>> HI, ASHLEIGH.
WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT IT, THIS IS
ABOUT TEN HOURS AGO ALMOST TO
THE MINUTE THAT ALL OF THIS WAS
GOING ON.
9:30 THIS MORNING IT WAS A
NORMAL START TO THE DAY AHERE.
600 STUDENTS HERE, 50 FACULTY
MEMBERS.
WE DON'T HAVE A COMPLETELY ON
THE LAYOUT OF THE SCHOOL OR THE
TIMELINE.
WE HAVE SOME IDEA, SO THE DAY
WAS GETTING UNDER WAY, HAD BEEN
UNDER WAY ABOUT 30 MINUTES.
THERE WAS A MEETING HAPPENING UP
HERE INVOLVING THE PRINCIPAL,
THE VICE-PRINCIPAL, A SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST, AND SEVERAL OTHER
ADULTS IN THIS AREA.
THEN, AROUND 9:40 AS BEST WE CAN
TELL FROM WITNESSES, JUST 10
MINUTES LATER, IT WOULD APPEAR
THAT'S WHEN THE GUNMAN ENTERS
THE BUILDING.
HOW DID HE DO IT?
JASON CARROLL MENTIONED THE NEW
SECURITY SYSTEM.
WE'RE NOT SURE HOW HE GOT PAST
THAT.
WE KNOW POLICE LOOKED HARD ALL
DAY AT A CAR PARKED IN THE FIRE
LANE.
IT'S STILL THERE, SURROUNDED BY
TAPE, AS BEST I CAN TELL.
THE SUGGESTION WOULD BE FROM
THIS AND FROM WITNESSES THAT IN
FACT SOMEHOW THE GUNMAN DID COME
RIGHT THROUGH THE FRONT DOOR
HERE INTO THE SCHOOL AND ALMOST
IMMEDIATELY PEOPLE THROUGHOUT
THIS BUILDING REPORTED HEARING
GUNFIRE.
9:41.
THAT'S WHEN THE CALLS STARTED
COMING IN TO 911.
THE PRINCIPAL, THE
VICE-PRINCIPAL, AND THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST WHO WERE IN THIS
MEETING, ACCORDING TO THE
WITNESSES, WENT INTO THE HALL
AND WENT TOWARD THAT GUNFIRE TO
SEE WHAT WAS HAPPENING.
THERE WAS SHOUTING, MANY SHOUTS
AND SHOTS AND THE VICE-PRINCIPAL
CAME BACK INTO THE MEETING ROOM
WOUNDED BUT THE OTHER TWO DID
NOT.
AUTHORITIES SAY ALL OF THE
SHOOTING HAPPENED REALLY IN A
RELATIVELY SHORT PERIOD OF TIME
AND THEY SAY THE GUNMAN DID NOT
ROAM AROUND BUT GENERALLY STAYED
IN JUST TWO ROOMS AND A HALLWAY
RIGHT UP HERE.
THAT'S IN FACT WHERE THEY
ULTIMATELY FOUND HIM.
9:45.
TEACHERS WERE TRYING TO PROTECT
STUDENTS ALL THROUGHOUT THIS
SCHOOL.
SOME STUDENTS WERE NEAR THE
GYMNASIUM, WERE TOLD TO HIDE IN
CLOSETS.
OTHERS STUDENTS IN OTHER PARTS
OF THE BUILDING SAY THEY WERE
LED OUTSIDE TO FLEE.
IT'S NOT REALLY CLEAR IF THAT
HAPPENED WITH THE TEACHERS OR
LATER WITH THEM BEING HELPED OUT
BY SOME SORT OF LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS.
NONETHELESS, WE KNOW THAT THERE
WAS A REAL EFFORT THROUGHOUT THE
SCHOOL TO GET ALL OF THESE KIDS
INTO SOME SORT OF SAFETY.
THIS PICTURE BY THE WAY FROM
"THE NEWTOWN BEE."
THERE WERE ALL THESE TEACHERS
TRYING TO DO SOMETHING ABOUT IT,
THEY DIDN'T REALLY KNOW WHAT WAS
GOING ON.
IT'S NOT CLEAR AT WHAT POINT IN
THIS PROCESS THE GUNMAN DIED.
LAW OFFICIALS SAY NO OFFICERS
FIRED A WEAPON, BUT THEY DID
FIND HIM DEAD IN ONE OF THE
ROOMS THERE.
THE SUGGESTION BEING PROBABLY
THAT HE KILLED HIMSELF.
BUT WE'LL GET MORE DETAILS OF
THAT AS WE GO ON.
THIS IS WHAT WE DO KNOW.
WHEN LAW ENFORCEMENT AGENTS
ARRIVED AT THE SCHOOL, THEY
IMMEDIATELY SET UP A PERIMETER
AROUND IT.
IT WAS STATE AND LOCAL POLICE.
AND OFFICERS SPREAD THROUGHOUT
THE BUILDING.
THEY SAY THEY ENTERED
IMMEDIATELY TO SECURE ROOMS TO
FIND STUDENTS AND TO MAKE SURE
IF A GUN MAN WAS STILL ACTIVE
THAT THEY GOT HIM UNDER CONTROL
OR KILLED THEM IF THEY HAD TO.
THEN THEY QUICKLY STARTED
LEADING STUDENTS AWAY FROM THE
SCHOOL, TRYING TO GET THEM OUT
TO SAFETY.
THIS WAS JUST A HORRENDOUS,
HORRENDOUS EVENT, AS YOU KNOW.
VERY DIFFICULT EVEN FOR THE
OFFICERS WHO WERE INVOLVED
BECAUSE THEY HAD TO, AS YOU
SAID, TELL MANY OF THESE
CHILDREN, AVERT YOUR EYES, CLOSE
YOUR EYES, BECAUSE THEY KNEW
THEY WERE GOING TO LEAD THEM
RIGHT PAST MANY OF THE VICTIMS.
ASHLEIGH, WE DON'T KNOW IF THIS
IS THE EXACT TIMELINE BUT THIS
IS A PRETTY GOOD IDEA OF WHAT
HAPPENED.
AGAIN, TEN HOURS AGO ALMOST TO
THE MINUTE.
ASHLEIGH?
>> IT ALL SEEMED TO TRANSPIRE SO
QUICKLY, AS YOU SAID, IN SUCH A
CONCENTRATED WAY, TOM.
IT'S OVERWHELMING TO THINK OF
WHAT WAS HAPPENING AS THESE
CHILDREN WERE DYING.
AND WE SHOULD ALSO NOTE AS I SAY
THOSE BODIES ARE STILL WHERE
THEY LAY IN THAT SCHOOL AWAITING
A POSITIVE I.D.
PRESUMABLY THE BODY OF THE
SHOOTER IS STILL THERE AS WELL.
AWAITING THE POSITIVE I.D.
I'M JOINED BY CONGRESSMAN ROSA
DELAURA VE IN WASHINGTON, D.C.
AT THE MONUMENT.
THIS MUST HAVE BEEN OVERWHELMING
NEWS.
HOW ARE YOU PROCESSING ALL OF
THIS INFORMATION WHERE YOU ARE?
>> WELL, IT'S REALLY -- IT IS
OVERWHELMING, ASHLEIGH.
IT'S UNTHINKABLE, WHAT HAPPENED
TODAY.
IT HITS SO CLOSE TO HOME FOR ALL
OF US.
AND OBVIOUSLY OUR THOUGHTS, OUR
PRAYERS, ARE WITH THE FAMILIES,
WITH THE SIBLINGS, WITH PEOPLE
WHO HAVE SUFFERED SUCH A TRAGIC
LOSS.
I'M IN WASHINGTON THIS WEEKEND
BECAUSE -- TO BE WITH MY
GRANDCHILDREN WHO LIVE IN
WASHINGTON, D.C.
THEY'RE 8, 5 1/2, 5, AND 3.
SO THIS IS -- REALLY HILTS SO
CLOSE TO HOME.
AND THESE BEAUTIFUL, YOUNG
ANGELS WHO HAD SO MUCH TO LIVE
FOR.
AND IT SEEMS SO SENSELESS.
AND AS I SAID, UNTHINKABLE THAT
THIS COULD HAPPEN.
BUT IT HAS.
AND NOW THE PRESIDENT SAID, YOU
KNOW, WE COME TOGETHER, WE WRAP
OUR ARMS AROUND THESE FAMILIES
AND WE HOLD THEM DEAR AND CLOSE
TO OUR HEARTS.
AND WE REMEMBER REALLY TO LOVE
ONE ANOTHER AND TO LOVE OUR
CHILDREN AND TELL THEM THAT AND
HUG THEM EVERY DAY.
SO THAT THEY KNOW THE DEPTH OF
FEELING.
AND IT IS -- WHAT AN ENORMOUS
TRAGEDY.
NOT JUST FOR CONNECTICUT BUT FOR
THE ENTIRE COUNTRY.
>> IT REALLY HAS BROUGHT OUT AN
INCREDIBLE PERSONAL SORROW IN SO
MANY PEOPLE WHO ARE CONNECTED TO
THIS, WHETHER THEY BE SEASONED
JOURNALISTS WHO HAVE SPENT 25
YEARS OWN AND SEEN IT ALL, OR A
CONGRESSWOMAN LIKE YOURSELF.
MANY OF US ARE PARENTS.
I MYSELF AM A PARENT OF TWO
SMALL CHILDREN.
THEY GO TO SCHOOL AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL ABOUT 25
MINUTES AWAY FROM HERE.
THIS HAS BEEN AN OVERWHELMING
DAY FOR MANY PEOPLE.
I WANT TO ASK IF YOU'VE BEEN IN
CONTACT WITH THE PRESIDENT OR
ANY OF THE AUTHORITIES WHO MAY
BE ABLE TO LEND A HAND TO THIS
COMMUNITY AND AVAIL THEMSELVES
OF ALL THE ASSISTANCE THAT THIS
COMMUNITY'S UNDOUBTEDLY GOING TO
NEED IN THE DAYS AND MONTHS
AHEAD.
>> WE HAVE BEEN IN TOUCH WITH
THE GOVERNOR'S OFFICE.
AS THE PRESIDENT SAID, THAT HE
HAS BEEN IN TOUCH WITH GOVERNOR
MALLOY.
AND HE SAID THAT, YOU KNOW,
WHATEVER SERVICES CONNECTICUT
NEEDS WILL BE AVAILABLE AND THE
GOVERNOR AS WELL TALKED ABOUT,
AGAIN, HOW WE WILL EMBRACE THESE
FAMILIES.
AND I KNOW THE ENTIRE DELEGATION
FEELS THAT WAY.
AND SENATOR DODD WAS HERE THIS
EVENING AS WELL WITH HIS
DAUGHTER GRACE.
AND SO THERE WAS A TREMENDOUS
OUTPOURING OF SUPPORT.
AND EACH IN OUR OWN WAY WILL TRY
TO ACCESS THE SERVICES THAT
THESE FAMILIES WILL NEED.
NOT JUST TODAY OR TOMORROW OR
THE NEXT FEW WEEKS BUT ONGOING.
>> CONGRESSMAN ROSA DeLAURO, I'M
SO SORRY FOR YOU AND YOUR
NEIGHBORS AND CONSTITUENTS AND
THE HEARTS OF THE NATION ARE
WITH YOU TONIGHT.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US FROM
THE VIGIL AT THE WASHINGTON
MONUMENT.
COMING UP, I'M GOING TO TAKE YOU
TO ANOTHER VISIBLE JILL.
THERE ARE SO MANY.
IF PEOPLE AREN'T HOLDING VIGIL
IN THEIR OWN HOMES TONIGHT, AT
LEAST THE PEOPLE IN THIS
COMMUNITY HAVE HEADED TO TWO
LOGICAL CHURCHES.
AT ONE OF THOSE VIGIL S YOU'RE
GOING TO HEAR FROM THE GOVERNOR
DAN MALLOY AND HOW HE IS
REACHING OUT TO THE PEOPLE WHO
LIVE HERE WHO ARE BEWILDERED AND
SHOCKED BY WHAT'S HAPPENED HERE
TODAY.
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
>>> WE'RE LIVE WITH BREAKING
NEWS IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, A
SMALL TOWN IN THE SOUTHWESTERN
PART OF THIS STATE THAT HAS BEEN
FACED WITH THE WORST EVIL
ACCORDING TO THIS STATE'S
GOVERNOR THAT THEY WILL EVER
LIKELY SEE.
EVEN THE PRESIDENT HAD TO WIPE
AWAY TEARS TODAY AS HE OFFERED
HIS SUPPORT TO THE FAMILIES OF
THE VICTIMS OF THIS TERRIBLE
SCHOOL SHOOTING IN CONNECTICUT.
HERE'S SOME OF PRESIDENT OBAMA'S
REMARKS EARLIER TODAY.
>> THIS AFTERNOON, I SPOKE WITH
GOVERNOR MALLOY AND FBI DIRECTOR
MUELLER.
I OFFERED GOVERNOR MALLOY MY
CONDOLENCES ON BEHALF OF THE
NATION AND MADE IT CLEAR HE WILL
HAVE EVERY SINGLE RESOURCE THAT
HE NEEDS TO INVESTIGATE THIS
HEINOUS CRIME, CARE FOR THE
VICTIMS, COUNSEL THEIR FAMILIES.
WE'VE ENDURED TOO MANY OF THESE
TRAGEDIES IN THE PAST FEW YEARS.
AND EACH TIME I LEARN THE NEWS,
I REACT NOT AS A PRESIDENT BUT
AS ANYBODY ELSE WOULD.
AS A PARENT.
AND THAT WAS ESPECIALLY TRUE
TODAY.
I KNOW THERE'S NOT A PARENT IN
AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN --
>> WE'VE BEEN GETTING UPDATES
REGULARLY, AND SOMETIMES WE GET
IDENTIFICATIONS, SOMETIMES WE
GET A STANDBY.
LET'S GO LIVE AND SEE WHAT'S
BEING SAID.
>> THIS IS A CASE OF EXTREMELY
LARGE MAGNITUDE, AS YOU KNOW,
BETWEEN NEWTOWN AND STATE POLICE
AND OUR FEDERAL PARTNERS THAT WE
UTILIZE.
EVEN SOME OUT-OF-STATE PARTNERS
WILL HELP US REACH OUT OF STATE
IF ANYTHING CROSSES THE STATE
BORDERS.
IT'S GOING TO TAKE A LONG TIME.
WE WILL BE PROCESSING THIS
BUILDING AND I'M JUST
SPECULATING RIGHT NOW, BUT AT
LEAST UNTIL SUNDAY.
>> SIR, HAVE THE PARENTS BEEN
GIVEN ACCESS TO THE BODIES OF
THE DECEASED CHILDREN?
>> NO.
>> HOW ARE YOU MANAGING
IDENTIFICATIONS?
>> WE HAVE A PROCESS IN PLACE
THAT WE'RE GOING TO ESTABLISH.
WE HAVE A PROCESS ESTABLISHED, I
SHOULD SAY, IN PLACE THAT WE'RE
GOING TO UTILIZE TO IDENTIFY
EACH INDIVIDUAL.
>> LIEUTENANT, DO YOU EXPECT
THAT -- THE IDENTIFICATION TO
TAKE INTO TOMORROW OR --
>> WE'RE CAUTIOUSLY OPTIMISTIC
WE CAN HAVE POSITIVE I.D.s BY
TOMORROW.
THE PROFESSIONALS THAT ARE
TELLING US THAT, SPECIFICALLY
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER AND HIS
TEAM, OUR INVESTIGATORS, AND
WORKING TOGETHER, WE'RE HOPING
TO ACCOMPLISH THAT.
>> DOES THAT INCLUDE THE BODY OF
THE OTHER --
>> THE FAMILIES HAVE BEEN
NOTIFIED.
PRELIMINARY IDENTIFICATIONS HAVE
BEEN MADE.
THROUGH PROCESS OF ELIMINATION,
UNFORTUNATELY, THE FAMILIES HAVE
BEEN TOLD.
BUT AGAIN, WE WANT TO BE
ABSOLUTELY, POSITIVELY SURE, NO
DOUBT WHATSOEVER.
>> WE SAW FBI ON THE SCENE
EARLIER WHEN IT WAS CRAZY.
>> YES.
>> WHAT WAS THEIR ROLE?
IS THERE STILL A ROLE FOR THEM
RIGHT NOW?
>> CERTAINLY THEY'RE WITH US,
WORKING WITH US, THEY WERE
FEDERAL PARTNERS HERE, FBI, ATF,
ALL OFFERING SERVICES IN ANY
SPECIALIZATION THEY HAVE,
OFFERING ABILITY ACROSS STATE
LINES.
SIMPLY STATED, EVERYONE'S COME
TOGETHER IN THE LAW ENFORCEMENT
COMMUNITY.
THIS IS A MASSIVE INVESTIGATION.
SO MANY LAW ENFORCEMENT AGENCIES
DON'T EVER HAVE TO UNDERTAKE.
NEWTOWN AND STATE POLICE WORKING
SIDE BY SIDE UTILIZING ANY
RESOURCE WE MIGHT NEED AND WE'RE
APPRECIATIVE OF ANY HELP WE'RE
GETTING.
>> [ INAUDIBLE ]
ANYONE BUT THE PERPETRATOR
INVOLVED, ANY COME MISSION?
>> NO, AT THIS POINT IN TIME
WE'RE CONFIDENT WE HAVE THE
SHOOTER.
>> [ INAUDIBLE ] SPECIFIC
CLASSROOM?
>> NO, I'D RATHER NOT DO THAT,
QUITE FRANKLY.
I'VE BEEN A TROOPER A LONG TIME
AND MY LIEUTENANT TO MY LEFT HAS
BEEN IN LAW ENFORCEMENT A LONG
TIME.
IT'S JUST SOMETHING THAT SERVES
NO USEFUL PURPOSE.
IT'S RATHER NOT GET INTO THAT.
IT'S A HORRIFIC SCENE.
BETWEEN OUR MUTUAL EXPERIENCE,
AND WE'VE NEVER SEEN ANYTHING
LIKE THIS, IT'S HEART-WRENCHING
FOR US AS IT IS FOR THE
FAMILIES.
I JUST WOULD LIKE TO JUST LEAVE
THAT --
>> DID THE SHOOTER HAVE A
HISTORY WITH THE SCHOOL?
DID HE ATTEND THE SCHOOL?
>> I THINK WHAT WE'VE GOT TO
DO -- WE'RE LOOKING AT THAT.
WE'RE LOOKING AT ALL THE
HISTORY.
WE'LL GO BACKWARDS AS FAR AS WE
HAVE TO GO IN THIS
INVESTIGATION.
AND HOPEFULLY WE'LL STUMBLE ON
ANSWERS AND WE'LL
ANSWERS AND HOPEFULLY NOT
DEVELOP MANY MORE QUESTIONS.
WE WANT TO BUILD THE PROCESS AND
THE STORY.
AN INVESTIGATION IS LIKE A
PUZZLE.
WE WANT TO FORM A COMPLETE
PICTURE SO THAT ANYONE CAN TRULY
UNDERSTAND WHAT OCCURRED.
I WOULD LIKE TO SAY THAT KEY
WILL COME BACK TOMORROW IN THE
MORNING SAY 8:00 IN THE MORNING
TO LET YOU KNOW HOW WE
PROGRESSED OVERNIGHT.
AS WE PREPARE THE LIST OF
POSITIVE IDENTIFICATIONS, I WANT
TO DO ONE LIST.
NOT A PIECE MEAL.
NOT A COUPLE HERE AND A COUPLE
THERE.
ONE FINAL LIST.
THE MINUTE THAT'S DONE, WE WILL
BE HERE WITH IT AND ALSO POST IT
ON OUR WEBSITE SO IT'S AVAILABLE
TO EVERYBODY.
>> WHAT'S THE TIMELINE --
>> OF YOUR OFFICERS, WITH THIS
SITUATION THE WAY THEY WERE ABLE
TO GET THE KIDS OUT OF THERE AND
GET THEM HOME AND AS MANY OUT AS
QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE.
>> THESE GUYS WHEN THEY GOT TO
THE DOOR AND WERE FIRST IN THE
DOOR AND THE SURROUNDING PDs AND
THE TROOPERS, THEIR TRAINING
KICKED IN.
THIS IS SOMETHING YOU TRAIN FOR
AND PLAN FOR.
YOU WORK TOWARDS AND HOPE TO
NEVER HAVE TO USE.
THEIR TRAINING KICKED IN AND
THEY SAVED A LOT OF LIVES AND
DID A GREAT JOB.
>> CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT THE
SHOOTER?
WHAT CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT THE
>> I WOULD RATHER DO THAT IN THE
MORNING WHEN WE HAVE POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATION EVEN OF THE
SHOOTER.
WE WILL HAVE ALL THAT
INFORMATION AND HOPEFULLY TIE UP
LOOSE ENDS FIRST THING IN THE
MORNING.
I WOULD LIKE TO LEAVE IT WHERE
WE ARE RIGHT NOW AND WE WILL
FILL IN THE VOIDS TOMORROW AS
MUCH AS WE CAN.
>> WHAT'S YOUR TIMELINE FOR THE
OTHER CRIME SCENE?
-- [INAUDIBLE]
.
>> THE MEDICAL EXAMINER IS
MANAGING THE CASES OF THE DEAD.
THEY REQUEST ASSISTANCE AND
EQUIPMENT THAT IS BROUGHT IN FOR
HIM.
THEY ARE THERE WORKING NOW.
>> HOW DID YOU FIRST HEAR ABOUT
THE SHOOTING?
WHAT DID THEY SAY OR WHAT WAS
THE FIRST WORD YOU HAD?
>> IN A NUT SHELL, IT WAS 911
CALLS THAT CAME INTO NEWTOWN
STATE POLICE AND RESPONSE WAS
INSTANTANEOUS.
>> FROM WITHIN THE SCHOOL?
>> FROM SCHOOL SOURCES.
>> MULTIPLE CALLS?
>> I'M NOT SURE.
YES, I BELIEVE SO, BUT I DON'T
KNOW HOW MANY.
>> THEY ARE INVESTIGATING WITH
ANY THAT CAN ASSIST THEM IN
THEIR PORTION OF THE
INVESTIGATION.
THERE HAVE BEEN TWO OR THREE
DIFFERENT LOCATIONS MENTIONED,
BUT NOTE TO READ INTO THAT.
IF THERE IS SOMETHING
SIGNIFICANT ABOUT REACHING OVER
A STATE LINE OR DOING SOMETHING
THAT MAY BE RELATED TO THE CASE,
WE ARE NOT GOING TO HIDE IT.
WE WILL MAKE IT AVAILABLE AND
PROVIDE YOU WITH THAT
INFORMATION.
DON'T READ SOMETHING INTO IT
BECAUSE YOU HEAR THAT WE HAVE
GONE TO AUTHORITY IN ANOTHER
STATE.
THAT DOESN'T MEAN ANYTHING
REALLY.
>> THERE HAVE BEEN A NUMBER OF
RESOURCES HERE FOR THAT.
HOW ARE YOU DELEGATING THIS
SCENE WITH REGARDS TO THE STATE?
>> IT'S WORKING FINE.
WE HAVE PEOPLE ON EXTENDED
SHIFTS AND SUFFICE IT TO SAY
EVERYBODY -- ALL HANDS ON DECK.
WE WILL DO WHATEVER IT TAKES TO
ACCOMPLISH IT IN A TIMELY
FASHION.
I WILL END IT BECAUSE I WOULD
LIKE TO GIVE YOU GUYS A BREAK
AND WE WILL BE BACK AT 8:00
TOMORROW MORNING HERE.
THANK YOU.
>> THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
GIVING WHAT HE SAID WOULD BE THE
LAST BRIEFING OF THIS EVENING.
A COUPLE OF THE HEADLINES FROM
WHAT HE SAID.
HE SAID THIS WAS A HORRIFIC
SCENE AND WE HAD NEVER SEEN
ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
HE SAID THE RESPONSE WAS INSTANT
T
AND PREVENTED THE FURTHER LOSS
OF LIVES.
ONE OF THE THINGS HE MENTIONED
WHICH BEARS REPEATING IS THE
PROCESS OF ELIMINATION HAS SO
FAR BEEN HOW PEOPLE HAVE FOUND
OUT THAT THEY MAY HAVE LOST
THEIR OWN CHILDREN.
THERE HAVE BEEN NO POSITIVE IDs
MADE.
THEY ARE WORKING FEVERISHLY IN
THE SCHOOL.
THEY HAVE A LOT OF BODIES.
26 BODIES TO PROCESS.
A SCENE AS YOU HEARD IS
HORRIFIC.
BY THE PROCESS OF ELIMINATION,
PARENTS WHO ARE NOT UNIFIED AND
REUNITED WITH THEIR CHILDREN NOW
OFFICIALLY KNOW THEY LIKELY
NEVER WILL BE.
BACK IN A MOMENT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
AND HIS NEW BOSS TOLD HIM
TWO THINGS --
COOK WHAT YOU LOVE,
AND SAVE YOUR MONEY.
JOE DOESN'T KNOW IT YET,
BUT HE'LL WORK HIS WAY UP
FROM BUSSER TO WAITER TO CHEF
BEFORE OPENING A RESTAURANT
SPECIALIZING IN FISH AND GAME
FROM THE GREAT NORTHWEST.
HE'LL START INVESTING EARLY,
HE'LL FIND SOME GOOD PEOPLE
TO HELP GUIDE HIM,
AND HE'LL SET MONEY ASIDE
FROM HIS FIRST DAY OF WORK
TO HIS LAST,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
WHY THEY HAVE A
RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
TONIGHT OUR GUEST,
THOMAS SARGENT.
NOBEL LAUREATE
IN ECONOMICS,
AND ONE OF THE MOST CITED
ECONOMISTS IN THE WORLD.
PROFESSOR SARGENT,
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT CD RATES WILL
BE IN TWO YEARS?
NO.
IF HE CAN'T, NO ONE CAN.
THAT'S WHY ALLY HAS
A RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
ALLY BANK.
YOUR MONEY NEEDS AN ALLY.
Wooohooo....Hahaahahaha!
Oh...there you go.
I'm gonna stand
up to her!
No you're not.
I know.
You know Ronny folks who save
hundreds of dollars
switching to GEICO
sure are happy.
How happy are they Jimmy?
Happier than a witch in
a broom factory.
Get happy. Get GEICO.
Fifteen minutes could save you
fifteen percent or more.
>>> THE BODIES OF 20 CHILDREN,
SIX ADULTS AND SHOOTER REMAIN IN
A SCHOOL AFTER A HORRIFIC SCENE
UNFOLDED AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THE PROCESS WILL BE METICULOUS
TO DO THE POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATION.
THAT'S NECESSARY IN THIS
FORENSIC INVESTIGATION AFTER A
DAY THAT HAS BEEN SEARCHING AND
TRYING TO FIND THOSE WHO COULD
BE RESPONSIBLE OR MIGHT HAVE
INFORMATION.
AS WE NOTICE KNOW, 20-YEAR-OLD
ADAM LANZA IS ALSO DEAD IN THE
SCHOOL, THE SHOOTER APPARENTLY.
HIS BROTHER, 24-YEAR-OLD RYAN
LANZA TAKEN IN FOR QUESTIONING
FROM HOBOKEN, NOT A SUSPECT, BUT
IN FOR QUESTIONING AND NANCY
LANZA, THE MOTHER OF THE TWO
BOYS FOUND DEAD IN HER SON'S
RESIDENCE.
THE SCENES THAT EMERGED WERE SO
ASTOUNDING AS PEOPLE BEGAN TO
THE MAGNITUDE OF WHAT TRANSPIRED
HERE.
TAKE A LOOK.
>> OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN TODAY.
>> A HORRIFIC AND DIFFICULT
SCENE.
>> HE HAD BULLETS GOING BY HIM
AND SHE GRABBED HIM AND ANOTHER
CHILD AND PULLED THEM INTO A
CLASSROOM.
>> PEOPLE WENT OUT INTO THE HALL
AND ONLY ONE PERSON CAME BACK.
>> THEY TOLD US THAT EVERYBODY
THAT IS MISSING AND PRESUMED
MISSING IS IN THE SCHOOL AND
THEY ARE DEAD.
>> IT WAS MAYHEM IN THE ROOM
WITH ALL THE KIDS AND TEACHERS
TRYING TO FIND YOUR KID AND