GOOD EVENING, EVERYONE.
I'M ANDERSON COOPER IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
A TOWN THAT'S HEAVY WITH GRIEF,
LOSS AND A PROFOUND, PROFOUND
SILENT SADNESS.
A SHORT TIME AGO, STATE POLICE
PUT NAMES TO THE NUMBERS THEY
IDENTIFIED BY NACHL THE 20
CHILDREN AND SIX ADULT WOMEN
SHOT DEAD IN THEIR SCHOOL.
THE KIDS, ALL OF THEM, WERE
EITHER 6 YEARS OLD OR 7 YEARS
O
OLD.
MOST OF THEM WERE GIRLS.
ONE YOUNG VICTIM'S FATHER, A MAN
WHO WANTS TO SPEAK, A MAN WHO
WANTS YOU TO KNOW ABOUT HIS
LITTLE GIRL WHO WAS LOST.
YOU'RE GOING TO HEAR TRUE
ACCOUNTS OF REALLY REMARKABLE
BRAVERY, SHOWN BY PEOPLE,
TEACHERS INSIDE THAT SCHOOL
YESTERDAY.
THERE'S A LOT WE WANT TO TELL
YOU ABOUT IN THIS HOUR.
WE ALSO JUST FOUND OUT THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL BE VISITING
HERE TOMORROW TO SHOW HIS
SUPPORT FOR THE FAMILIES, TO
MEET WITH THE FIRST RESPONDERS
AND TO MOURN LOSS WITH ALL OF
THEM AND WITH THE NEIGH.
♪ HOLY NIGHT
ALL IS CALM ♪
♪ ALL IS BRIGHT
>> A LITTLE WHILE AGO IN STRAT
FORD, CONNECTICUT, ABOUT 20
MILES FROM HERE, FAMILY AND
FRIENDS OF ONE OF THE TEACHERS
KILLED YESTERDAY, VICTORIA SOTO
GATHERED TO REMEMBER HER AND
SHARE THEIR SADNESS.
VICKI SOTO WAS A FIRST GRADE
TEACHER, 27 YEARS OLD, ONE OF
THE SIX ADULTS SHOT YESTERDAY
INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
AND BACK HERE IN NEWTOWN, I WANT
YOU TO HEAR SOME VOICES FROM
THIS COMMUNITY.
THIS COMMUNITY TONIGHT OF PEOPLE
WHO ARE ANGUISHED, FAMILY
MEMBERS AND THE PROFESSIONALS
WHO HAD TO OVERCOME THEIR SHOCK
AND THEIR GRIEF TO DO THEIR
JOBS.
>> ALL THE ONES THAT I KNOW OF
BY THE ONE WEAPON.
I ONLY DID SEVEN OF THE
AUTOPSIES, THE VICTIMS I HAD
RANGED FROM 3 TO 11 ROUNDS A
PIECE.
AND I ONLY SAW TWO OF THEM WITH
POST RANGE SHOOTING.
>> EMILIE ALICE PARKER WAS THE
SWEETEST LITTLE GIRL I'VE EVER
KNOWN.
MY CHILDREN ARE GRIEVING, MY
SIBLINGS ACROSS THE COUNTRY ARE
GRIEVING, AND WE'RE JUST
DEVASTATED THAT SOMEONE SO
BEAUTIFUL AND PERFECT IS NO
LONGER GOING TO BE IN OUR LIVES.
AND FOR NO REASON.
AND WE CAN ONLY PRAY THAT WE
FIND UNDERSTANDING IN THE DAYS
AND WEEKS TO COME.
>> WOW.
A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE SEARCHING
FOR UNDERSTANDING TONIGHT.
I JUST WANT TO POINT OUT.
YOU ALL KNOW THE NAME OF THE
SHOOTER BY NOW, AND WE WANT YOU
TO KNOW THE NAMES OF THE
VICTIMS.
SO WE'RE REALLY GOING TO BE
FOCUSING ON THEM AS MUCH AS WE
CAN TONIGHT, AND, OF COURSE, IN
THE DAYS AHEAD ON THIS PROGRAM.
I'M NOT GOING TO KEEP REPEATING
THE NAME OF THE SHOOTER BECAUSE
YOU ALREADY KNOW IT I DON'T WANT
THAT NAME TO GO DOWN IN HISTORY
AND I THINK A LOT OF PEOPLE HERE
IN THIS TOWN DO NOT WANT THE
NAME OF THE PERSON, THE KILLER,
TO BE KNOWN IN HOUSEHOLDS AND TO
GO DOWN IN HISTORY.
THEY WANT THE NAMES OF THE
VICTIMS TO BE REMEMBERED.
AND WE WILL REMEMBER THEM
TONIGHT.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI IS JOINING ME
NOW WITH THE LATEST ON THE
INVESTIGATION.
YOU WERE IN NEWTOWN JUST HOURS
AFTER THE SHOOTING HAPPENED,
SUSAN.
WHAT ARE YOU HEARING FROM PEOPLE
TODAY?
>> WELL, WE'RE HEARING THAT
EVERYONE WANTS TO FIND OUT WHY,
WHY THIS HAPPENED.
WHAT LED THIS YOUNG MAN TO DO
THIS.
AND WE KNOW THAT AUTHORITIES ARE
TRACING HIM WAY BACK, AS FAR AS
THEY CAN GO, BUT PRIMARILY
CONCENTRATE ON THE TIME HE WAS A
TEENAGER UP UNTIL NOW WHEN HE'S
20 YEARS OLD.
AND, IN FACT, CNN OBTAINED A
PHOTOGRAPH, ONE TAKEN IN 2005
WHEN HE WOULD HAVE BEEN ABOUT 13
YEARS OLD.
WE ALSO KNOW THAT AUTHORITIES
HAVE BEEN SPENDING THE ENTIRE
DAY CHASING DOWN LEADS, ALSO
LOOKING AT ANYTHING HE WOULD
HAVE WRITTEN DOWN, LETTERS,
CORRESPONDENT.
AND THEY EVEN WENT TO VARIOUS
GUN RANGES AS WELL AS A SPORTING
GOODS STORE BECAUSE THEY GOT A
TIP, A TIP THAT THE SHOOTER HAD
GONE THERE TO PURCHASE A GUN ON
TUESDAY.
WELL, THEY TALKED TO THE
EMPLOYEES, THEY LOOKED HARD AT
ALL THE SURVEILLANCE VIDEOS FROM
THAT DAY AND THEY SAY THEY HAVE
NOT BEEN ABLE TO PULL ANYTHING
OUT OF THAT.
THAT LEAD JUST DID NOT PAN OUT.
BUT WE ALSO LEARNED FROM THE
ATF, AND EERSON THAT THEY FOUND
THREE MORE WEAPONS AT THE HOUSE
THAT THE YOUNG MAN SHARED WITH
HIS MOTHER.
NOW, THEY DIDN'T SAY WHAT THOSE
WEAPONS WERE, BUT MY SOURCES
TELL ME THEY ARE THREE OLDER
MODEL RIFLES.
AND SO THEY'VE BEEN TRACING, SO
FAR HAVE TRACED ONLY ONE OF THEM
TO HIS MOTHER.
ANDERSON?
>> AND WHAT DO WE KNOW NOW ABOUT
THE THREE WEAPONS THAT WERE
TAKEN INTO THE SCHOOL?
>> WELL, THOSE THREE WE NOW KNOW
ACCORDING TO OUR SOURCES THAT
ALL THREE OF THEM WERE FOUND
RIGHT THERE WITH THE SHOOTER.
THOSE WERE TWO HANDGUNS AND A
LONG GUN THAT WE NOW KNOW CALLED
A BUSHMASTER.
AND YOU HEARD THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER REFER TO THE LONG GUN
SPECIFICALLY TODAY.
HE SAID THAT THE SHOOTER USED
THAT LONG GUN TO KILL SEVERAL OF
HIS VICTIMS.
SOME WITH ANYWHERE FROM 3 TO 11
WOUNDS EACH, ANDERSON.
JUST A VICIOUS, COLD BLOODED
KILLING.
ANDERSON?
>> SUSAN CANDIOTTI, APPRECIATE
YOUR REPORTING TONIGHT.
WE'RE OBVIOUSLY BEING VERY
RESPECTFUL AND NOT APPROACHING
ANYBODY WHO IS IN MOURNING OR IN
LOSS.
AND WE CERTAINLY DON'T WANT TO
INTRUDE ON ANYBODY'S GRIEF, BUT
SOME FAMILIES ARE SPEAKING.
AND THEY DO WANT YOU TO KNOW
ABOUT THEIR CHILD, THEIR CHILD
WHO IS LOST.
WE JUST HEARD FROM THE FATHER OF
ONE LITTLE GIRL WHO WAS KILLED
YESTERDAY.
AND HE SAID I DON'T KNOW HOW TO
GET THROUGH SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
BUT THE MAN WHO SAID THOSE WORDS
WILL HAVE TO FIND A WAY, OF
COURSE.
AND SO WILL SO MANY OTHER
FAMILIES HERE.
HIS DAUGHTER, 6-YEAR-OLD EMILIE
PARKER WAS ONE OF THE CHILDREN
KILLED AND CARRYING THE
UNBEARABLE PAIN.
ROBBIE PARKER WENT BEFORE
CAMERAS TONIGHT TO TELL THE
WORLD ABOUT THAT PAIN AND ABOUT
HIS DAUGHTER.
AND SHOW HIS LOVE AND ADMIRATION
FOR THE LITTLE GIRL HE DESCRIBED
AS EXTRAORDINARY.
LISTEN.
>> MY NAME IS ROBBIE PARKER.
MY FAMILY IS ONE OF THE FAMILIES
THAT LOST A CHILD YESTERDAY IN
THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOLS HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
I'VE BEEN CONTACTED BY SO MANY
PEOPLE AND AGENCIES WANTING TO
KNOW HOW WE'RE DOING, AND I JUST
THOUGHT, YOU KNOW, THIS MIGHT BE
THE BEST WAY TO SHARE THOSE
FEELINGS WITH EVERYBODY.
FIRST OF ALL, I WOULD REALLY
LIKE TO OFFER OUR DEEPEST
CONDOLENCES TO THE FAMILIES
AFFECTED BY THIS SHOOTING.
IT'S A HORRIFIC TRAGEDY AND WE
WANT EVERYONE TO KNOW THAT OUR
HEARTS AND PRAYERS GO OUT TO
THEM.
I CAN'T IMAGINE HOW HARD THIS
EXPERIENCE MUST BE FOR YOU AND I
WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT OUR FAMILY
AND OUR LOVE AND SUPPORT GO OUT
TO YOU AS WELL.
AT THIS TIME, OUR THANKS GO OUT
TO SO MANY PEOPLE, SO MANY
FRIENDS AND FAMILY AND COMPLETE
STRANGERS WHO WE DON'T KNOW, FOR
ALL THE LOVE, CONDOLENCES AND
SUPPORT YOU'VE GIVEN US.
MY DAUGHTER EMILIE WOULD BE ONE
OF THE FIRST ONES TO BE STANDING
AND GIVING HER LOVE AND SUPPORT
TO ALL THOSE VICTIMS, BECAUSE
THAT'S THE TYPE OF PERSON THAT
SHE IS.
NOT BECAUSE OF ANY PARENTING
THAT MY WIFE AND I COULD HAVE
DONE, BUT BECAUSE THOSE WERE THE
GIFTS THAT WERE GIVEN TO HER BY
HER HEAVENLY FATHER.
AS THE DEEP PAIN BEGINS TO
SETTLE INTO OUR HEARTS, WE FIND
COMFORT, REFLECTING ON THE
INCREDIBLE PERSON THAT EMILY WAS
AND HOW MANY LIVES THAT SHE WAS
ABLE TO TOUCH IN HER SHORT TIME
HERE ON EARTH.
EMI
EMILIE WAS BRIGHT, CREATIVE AND
VERY LOVING.
EMILIE WAS ALWAYS WILLING TO TRY
NEW THINGS, OTHER THAN FOOD.
SHE TOUCHED THE LIVES OF
EVERYONE SHE CAME IN CONTACT
WITH.
SHECHS AN EXCEPTIONAL ARTIST AND
SHE ALWAYS CARRIED AROUND HER
MARKERS AND PENCILS SO SHE NEVER
MISSED AN TUPTD TO DRAW A
PICTURE OR MAKE A CARD FOR THOSE
AROUND HER.
I CAN'T COUNT THE NUMBER OF
TIMES EMILIE NOTICED SOMEONE
FEELING SAD OR FRUSTRATED AND
WOULD RUSH TO FIND A PIECE OF
PAPER TO DRAW THEM A PICTURE OR
TO WRITE THEM AN ENCOURAGING
NOTE.
EMILIE'S CARD MAKING WAS
EXPREZZED BEAUTIFULLY THIS LAST
OCTOBER WHEN SHE PLACED A VERY
SPECIAL CARD THAT SHE HAD MADE
INTO THE CASKET WITH HER GRANDPA
WHO ALSO JUST RECENT LLY DIED OA
TRAGIC ACCIDENT.
EMILIE WAS A MENTOR TO HER TWO
LITTLE SISTERS, DELIGHTING IN
TEACHING THEM HOW TO READ, DANCE
AND FIND THE SIMPLE JOYS IN
LIFE.
EMILIE'S LAUGHTER WAS INFECTIOUS
AND ALL THOSE WHO HAD THE
PLEASURE TO MEET HER WOULD AGREE
THAT THIS WORLD IS A BETTER
PLACE BECAUSE SHE HAS BEEN IN
IT.
AS WE MOVE ON FROM WHAT HAPPENED
HERE, WHAT HAPPENED TO SO MANY
PEOPLE, LET IT NOT TURN INTO
SOMETHING THAT DEFINES US.
SOMETHING THAT INSPIRES US TO BE
BETTER, TO BE MORE COMPASSIONATE
AND MORE HUMBLE PEOPLE.
LET'S PLEASE KEEP THE SENTIMENTS
OF LOVE THAT WE FEEL FOR OUR
FAMILIES AND THE COMPASSION THAT
WE FEEL FOR OTHERS, EVEN
COMPLETE STRANGERS, AND KEEP
THEM WITH US AT ALL TIMES.
NOT JUST IN THE TIMES OF SORROW
AND TRAGEDY.
AND LET'S DO THIS SO WE CAN MAKE
EVERYONE IN THIS COUNTRY FEEL
SAFE.
THANK YOU.
>> ROBBIE PARKER SPEAKING ABOUT
HIS DAUGHTER, EMILIE.
THAT'S EMILIE IN THE BOTTOM
RIGHT CORNER.
YOU TALKED ABOUT EMILIE BEING A
MENTOR TO HER SISTERS, EVEN AT
THE SENDER AGE OF 6 YEARS OLD.
IN THE COMING DAYS WE'RE GOING
TO BE HEARING MORE FROM PARENTS
WHO WANT YOU TO KNOW ABOUT THEIR
CHILDREN.
WE'RE GOING TO BE LEARNING MORE
ABOUT THE CHILDREN, AND IT JUST
ADDS TO THE HORROR OF THIS
EVENT.
THE THIS ENTIRE COMMUNITY FEELS.
WE WERE THERE WHEN ROBBIE PARKER
FACED THE CAMERAS.
I CAN'T -- THE STRENGTH FWR HIM
TO COME OUT AND SPEAK AT A TIME
WITH SUCH GRIEF AS WE TALK ABOUT
COMPASSION FOR OTHERS IS
EXTRAORDINARY.
>> IT'S INCREDIBLE.
TO STAND IF OUR OR FIVE FEET
AWAY FROM THE FATHER WHO JUST
LOST HIS DAUGHTER TO GUN
VIOLENCE AND THEN TALK ABOUT
COMPASSION AND NOT LETTING THIS
DEFINE ALL OF US.
AND HIS ADVICE TO OTHER PEOPLE,
THE NEED TO HEAL, THIS HAS GOT
TO BE SOMETHING THAT IMPROVES
SOCIETY OVERALL AND NOT JUST
FOCUSING ON HIS OWN PERSONAL
GRIEF.
IT IS AN EXTRAORDINARY MOMENT.
IN YOU THINK ABOUT ALL THE
PEOPLE YOU KNOW IN YOUR LIFE,
ESPECIALLY IF YOU'RE A PARENT
AND HAVE CHILDREN, TO IMAGINE
LOSING YOUR CHILD AND THEN BE
ABLE TO FACE REPORTERS TO SAY
THANK YOU FOR THE KINDNESS THAT
YOU RECEIVED IN THIS COUNTRY
JUST AS PEOPLE HAVE FOUND OUT
ABOUT IT.
FOR POSTING THINGS ON FACEBOOK.
IT'S REALLY QUITE EXTRAORDINARY.
AND WHEN I WAS SPEAKING FURTHER
FROM HIM, HE SAID LOOK, I'M NOT
ANGRY.
HE HAS TO FEEL THAT HE HAS TO BE
ABLE TO MOVE ON BY SHOWING
COMPASSION TO OTHERS SO OTHERS
CAN LEARN FROM WHAT HE IS GOING
THROUGH, NOT ONLY HIM, BUT HIS
SISTER-IN-LAW.
HERE'S WHAT SHE TOLD REPORTERS
JUST BEFORE HER FATHER SPOKE.
>> OUR FAMILY IS FROM UTAH.
I GOT A CALL YESTERDAY MORNING
FROM MY SISTER SAYING THERE HAD
BEEN A SHOOTING AND THERE WAS A
LOCKDOWN AT THE SCHOOL.
I WAS GIVING HER WORDS OF
COMFORT AS SHE WAS FRANTICALLY
ATTEMPTING TO FIND OUT WHAT WAS
GOING ON AND WHAT HAD HAPPENED.
AULD I COULD WAS ASSURE IN EVERY
OTHER INSTANCE WHEN A SHOOTING
HAPPENS, IT'S NOT THE 5, 6 AND 7
YEAR OLDS WHO ARE GOING TO BE
TARGETED.
THEY'RE TOO INNOCENT AND
PERFECT.
AS I TRIED TO REASSURE HER
THROUGHOUT THE DAY, AS I HOPPED
INTO AN AIRPLANE, AS I LEFT, I
DIDN'T KNOW THE STATUS OF MY
NIECE UNTIL WE ARRIVED IN
ATLANTA.
>> AND THAT'S IN LARGE PART WHY
THE FAMILY WANTED TO COME OUT
AND SPEAK TO REPORTERS.
SOMETHING ELSE I WANTED TO
MENTION IS THE FATHER ROBBIE IS
A PHYSICIANS ASSISTANT TREATING
CHILDREN.
THEY MOVED HERE EIGHT MONTHS
AGO.
TO LOSE THEIR CHILD LIKE THIS IS
REALLY UNFAIR, IT'S HARD TO
IMAGINE.
>> APPRECIATE IT, KIM.
GLAD YOU WERE THERE AND WE WERE
ABLE TO HEAR FROM ROBBIE ABOUT
HIS DAUGHTER.
YESTERDAY, WE SAW SOME TRULY
HEROIC EFFORTS BY TEACHERS, BY
SCHOOL ADMINISTRATORS, BY FIRST
RESPONDERS.
WHEN THE BULLETS STARTED FLYING,
SO MANY TEACHERS DID WHAT THEY
HAD PRACTICED.
THEY USHER CANNED THE KIDS YOUU.
THE AMAZING PART IS HOW TEACHERS
WERE ABLE TO KEEP THE KIDS CALM.
LISTEN TO SOME OF WHAT THEY HAD
TO SAY.
>> THEY HAD A SPOT IN THE ROOM
WHERE THEY WERE SUPPOSED TO GO
TO.
>> CAN YOU DESCRIBE THAT SPOT?
>> IT'S BETWEEN SOME BOOKCASES
AGAINST THE CALL, WHERE YOU
CAN'T BE SEEN BY ANY WINDOWS.
ONE OF OUR DOORS WASN'T LOCKED
SO WE WENT INTO A BACK STORAGE
ROOM AND LOCKED THE KIDS
TOGETHER.
>> HOW DID YOU KEEP THE KIDS
QUIET?
>> THERE WAS CRAYONS AND ERP PA
AND WEER TO SOME UP AND HAD THEM
COLOR.
>> WHAT DID YOU TELL THEM?
>> THERE WERE THREE OTHER ADULTS
WITH THEM.
THEY ASKED WHAT WAS GOING ON.
WE SAID WE DON'T KNOW.
WE ASKED THEM TO STAY QUIET.
IT MAY BE A DRILL, IT MAY NOT.
>> YOU DIDN'T KNOW AT THAT
POINT?
>> WE KNEW.
I CALLED THE OFFICE AND SHE TOLD
ME THERE WAS A SHOOTER.
>> THERE WAS POUND ON THE DOOR.
THEY SAID IT WAS THE POLICE.
WE DIDN'T WANT TO OPEN THE DOOR,
SO HE FIRST SLID A BADGE UNDER
THE DOOR, BUT WE HAD FILE
CABINETS IN FRONT OF IT SO WE
HAD TO MOVE THOSE.
>> ABOUT 9:30, 9:40, WE HEARD
NOISES.
AND THE ANNOUNCEMENT SYSTEM WAS
STILL ON.
IT DID GO OFF TO WHAT SOUNDED
LIKE POPS AND GUNSHOTS.
I'M NOT GOING TO TELL THAT TO
5-YEAR-OLDS.
I SAID WE'RE GOING TO A SAFE
AREA.
AND WE'RE GOING TO, YOU KNOW, WE
READ A STORY AND WE KEPT THEM
CALM.
>> THE TEACHER MANAGED TO TAKE
TWO CHILDREN OUT OF THE HALLWAY,
PULL THEM INTO THE CLASSROOM.
LOCKED THE DOOR AND MOVED
EVERYBODY OVER TO THE OTHER SIDE
OF THE ROOM.
>> WHEN I SAW THOSE TEACHERS AND
LOCKED EYES WITH EACH OF THOSE
SEPARATELY, WHEN I FOUND THE TWO
CHILDREN, IF I COULD GO BACK, I
WOULD EMBRACE THEM.
BECAUSE I HAD NO IDEA WHAT THEY
HAD GONE THROUGH.
>> ONE OF THE FIRST VICTIMS TO
BE PUBLICLY IDENTIFIED WAS
VICTORIA SOTO, 27 YEARS OLD, A
FIRST GRADE FEETEACHER.
SHE WAS KILLED IN HER CLASSROOM.
SHE'S BEING MOURNED TONIGHT,
HAILED AS A HERO.
JASON, HOW IS STRAT FORD
REMEMBERING THIS YOUNG WOMAN
TONIGHT?
THERE WAS A VIGIL EARLIER.
>> ANDERSON, THAT VIGIL JUST
WRAPPING UP A FEW MOMENTS AGO,
EVERYONE COMING OUT HERE
TONIGHT, LEANING ON EACH OTHER
FOR SUPPORT.
A LOT OF THOSE WHO ARE COMING
OUT HERE TONIGHT WORE GREEN.
GREEN WAS ONE OF SOTO'S FAVORITE
COLORS.
IN TERMS OF HOW THEY'RE
REMEMBERING HER, THEY'RE
REMEMBERING HER AS A DEDICATED
TEACHER.
THIS IS A YOUNG WOMAN WHO
ACTUALLY WANTED TO BE A TEACHER
EVER SINCE SHE HERSELF WAS A
LITTLE GIRL.
AND WHEN THEY CAME OUT HERE
TONIGHT, THEY SANG "AMAZING
GRACE."
THEY LIT CANDLES.
I ALSO EARLIER TODAY, ANDERSON,
HAD AN OPPORTUNITY TO SPEAK TO
ONE OF THE MEMBERS OF THE SOTO
FAMILY.
THEY TALKED A LITTLE BIT MORE
ABOUT HOW THEY WANT VICKI SOTO
TO BE REMEMBERED.
AND THEY ALSO TALKED ABOUT THE
HEROIC ACTIONS SHE TOOK IN HER
CLASSROOM TO SAVE HER STUDENTS.
>> THE FAMILY DIDN'T WANT VICKI
TO BE JUST ANOTHER VICTIM ON A
PIECE OF PAPER.
VICKI WAS AN OUTSTANDING
TEACHER, WELL LIKED, WELL
RESPECTED IN HER SCHOOL
COMMUNITY.
AND SHE WAS TAKEN TOO EARLY.
SHE INSTINCTIVELY WENT INTO
ACTION WHEN A MONSTER CAME INTO
HER CLASSROOM AND TRIED TO
PROTECT THE KIDS THAT SHE LOVED
SO MUCH.
>> CAN YOU TELL ME A LITTLE BIT
MORE ABOUT HOW SHE TRIED TO DO
THAT?
>> WHAT WE WERE TOLD WAS SHE
GATHERED HER CHILDREN INTO A
CLOSET AND PUT HERSELF IN HARM'S
WAY IN BETWEEN THE GUNMAN AND
THE KIDS.
AND WE JUST WANT THE PUBLIC TO
KNOW THAT VICKI WAS A HERO.
REGARDLESS OF THE INTIMATE
DETAILS OF WHAT TOOK PLACE IN
THAT CLASSROOM, VICKI WAS DOING
WHAT SHE KNEW WAS RIGHT IN HER
HEART AND WHAT SHE WAS TRAINED
TO DO TO PROTECT HER KIDS.
>> SO MANY TEARS HERE TONIGHT,
ANDERSON.
ALSO HERE TONIGHT WAS VICKI'S
FAMILY.
HER YOUNGER SISTER KALE LEE.
HER OTHER SISTER JULIAN, HER
YOUNGER BROTHER.
KALE LEE AT ONE POINT ADDRESSED
THE CROWD, ADDRESSED ALL THE
MOURNERS WHO CAME OUT HERE.
AND SHE SAID SOMETHING SHE
TWEETED A LITTLE EARLIER.
I'M GOING TO READ IT TO YOU
BRIEFLY.
HUG YOUR LOVED ONES.
TELL THEM HOW MUCH YOU LOVE THEM
BECAUSE YOU NEVER KNOW WHEN
YOU'LL SEE THEM AGAIN.
AND ONCE AGAIN, THE REASON WHY
THE FAMILY SAID THEY DECIDED TO
HOLD THIS VIGIL TONIGHT, WHY
THEY DECIDED TO RELEASE SOME OF
THE PICTURES THAT YOU SAW THERE
EARLIER OF VICKI SOTO IS THEY
DON'T WANT HER TO BE REMEMBERED
AS JUST A VICTIM, ANDERSON.
THEY WANT HER TO BE REMEMBERED
AS A WOMAN WHO WAS A DEDICATED
TEACHER, A WOMAN WHO WAS A
LOVING DAUGHTER, AND SOMEONE WHO
CARED FOR HER STUDENTS, SO MUCH
SO, ANDERSON, THAT SHE DIDN'T
EVEN REFER TO THEM AS STUDENTS,
SHE REFERRED TO THEM AS HER
CHILDREN.
ANDERSON?
>> I THINK SO MANY PARENTS WANT
PEOPLE TO KNOW ABOUT THEIR
CHILD, ABOUT THEIR SIBLING.
IF IT'S A TEACHER OR A SCHOOL
ADMINISTRATOR AND REALLY WANT TO
HONOR THE LIFE THAT THEY LIVED.
I THINK THAT'S AN IMPORTANT
POINT ABOUT NOT BEING REFERRED
TO AS A VICTIM, BUT AS A PERSON,
AS A SPIRIT WHO LIVED A
REMARKABLE LIFE.
AND IN THE CASE OF VICTORIA
SOTO, SACRIFICING HER LIFE TO
PROTECT HER STUDENTS, IT'S
EXTRAORDINARY.
YOU SPOKE WITH THE PARENTS OF A
YOUNG BOY WHO WAS IN VICTORIA
SOTO'S CLASS.
WE'VE HEARD FROM A LOT OF
PARENTS WHO ARE JUST SO THANKFUL
FOR ALL THE TEACHERS.
I IMAGINE THEY WERE AS WELL.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
THIS IS BRIANING ROBERT AND
DIANE LACATA.
THEY SAY IT'S IN PART HER QUICK
THINKING THAT'S PART OF THE
REASON WHY THEIR SON WAS ABLE TO
MAKE IT OUT OF THAT CLASSROOM
ALIVE, ANDERSON.
ALSO PART OF HIS OWN QUICK
THINKING AS SOMEHOW HE WAS ABLE,
ALONG WITH SEVERAL OTHER
STUDENTS TO RUN DIRECTLY PAST
THE GUNMAN AS HE WAS IN THE
CLASSROOM AND RUN OUT OF THE
SCHOOL TO SAFETY.
AND A VERY EMOTIONAL INTERVIEW I
DID WITH THESE PARENTS TODAY,
THEY ALSO CONVEYED THAT HAIR
SON, FOLLOWING THIS HORRIFIC
DAY, THEIR SON VERY MUCH LOVED
HIS TEACHER.
>> HE'S REASSURING HIMSELF THAT
HE'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
HE REALLY, REALLY, REALLY CARED
ABOUT HIS TEACHER.
HE KEEPS SAYING I HOPE SHE'S
OKAY, I HOPE IT'S NOT HER.
ENOS THAT SHE'S BEEN HURT, BUT
HE DOESN'T KNOW THE END RESULT.
HE KNOWS THE KIDS THAT HE SAW
GETTING SHOT.
HE DOESN'T KNOW THE OUTCOME.
SO I THINK HE'S REASSURING
HIMSELF IN HIS 6-YEAR-OLD MIND.
I KNOW HE'S PROCESSING IT, BUT I
THINK HE'S REASSURING HIMSELF.
I THINK HE'S TELLING HIMSELF
THAT IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
>> I DID SPEND B TIME WITH THE
TWO OF THEM.
THEIR SON IS VERY SHAKEN.
THEY HAD TO PUT A SIGN ON THEIR
DOORBELL TO ASK PEOPLE NOT TO
RING THE DOORBELL BECAUSE EVERY
TIME IT RINGS, AIDEN THINKS IT'S
THE BAD GUY COMING TO GET HIM.
NOW, AS HARD AS THIS DAY HAS
BEEN FOR THEIR FAMILY, THEY ALSO
SAID TO ME THAT THEIR HEARTS
BREAK FOR THE SO MANY OTHER
FAMILIES THAT CANNOT GO HOME TO
HUG THEIR CHILDREN TONIGHT AND
THEY WANTED TO MAKE SURE THAT
MESSAGE WAS CONVEYED, INCLUDING
TO THE FAMILY OF VICTORIA SOTO.
>> THERE'S STILL A LOT ABOUT THE
CHAIN OF R OF EVENTS THAT WE
DON'T KNOW.
WE'RE TRYING TO PIECE TOGETHER
THE PIECES AS BEST WE CAN.
AN UPDATE WHEN WE COME BACK.
[ Male Announcer ] THIS IS
JOE WOODS' FIRST DAY OF WORK.
AND HIS NEW BOSS TOLD HIM
TWO THINGS --
COOK WHAT YOU LOVE,
AND SAVE YOUR MONEY.
JOE DOESN'T KNOW IT YET,
BUT HE'LL WORK HIS WAY UP
FROM BUSSER TO WAITER TO CHEF
BEFORE OPENING A RESTAURANT
SPECIALIZING IN FISH AND GAME
FROM THE GREAT NORTHWEST.
HE'LL START INVESTING EARLY,
HE'LL FIND SOME GOOD PEOPLE
TO HELP GUIDE HIM,
AND HE'LL SET MONEY ASIDE
FROM HIS FIRST DAY OF WORK
TO HIS LAST,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
>> THE FIRST SHOTS RANG OUT AT
THE SANDY HOOK SCHOOL JUST AS
THE MORNING ANNOUNCEMENTS WERE
BEING READ OVER THE LOUD
SPEAKER, AS PEOPLE COULD HEAR
THE SOUNDS OF THE SHOOTING OVER
THE LOUD SPEAKER.
TOM FOREMAN IS IN WASHINGTON
WITH THE LATEST INFORMATION ON
WHAT WE HAVE ABOUT HOW THE DAY
UNFOLDED INSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
TOM?
>> ANDERSON, POLICE ARE
ESSENTIALLY CONSTRUCTING A MAP
OF ALL OF THE PLACES THAT MIGHT
HAVE HAD CONNECTIONS TO THIS
SHOOTER.
FOR EXAMPLE, HIS BROTHER'S
APARTMENT DOWN HERE IN NEW
JERSEY.
ACROSS NEW YORK UP INTO
CONNECTICUT, HIS MOTHER'S HOUSE
WHERE SHE WAS FOUND DEAD.
AND ONLY ABOUT THREE MILES AWAY,
OF COURSE, THE SCHOOL.
TO TRY TO FIGURE OUT WHAT LED
HIM TO THIS SPOT AT THAT TIME.
BECAUSE THEY DO BELIEVE THAT
SHORTLY AFTER MURDERING HIS
MOTHER, HE DID DRIVE THE FEW
MILES FROM HER HOUSE TO THIS
SCHOOL AND EMERGE IN THIS
PARKING LOT WITH WEAPONS VERY
MUCH LIKE THESE TO GO INTO THE
SCHOOL.
NOW, LET'S LOOK AT THE TIME LINE
OF WHAT HAPPENED.
THAT'S REALLY WHAT THEY'RE
TRYING TO RECONSTRUCT.
ABOUT 9:30 IN THE MORNING THAT'S
WHEN WE BELIEVE BASED ON
EYEWITNESS ACCOUNTS AND POLICE
RADIO THAT HE PROBABLY LEFT HIS
CAR.
WE THINK THIS IS THE ONE OVER
HERE, BASED ON THE
INVESTIGATION, AND CAME UP TO
THE FRONT OF THE SCHOOL.
THAT'S ALSO WHEN HE ENCOUNTERED
HIS FIRST OBSTACLES, BECAUSE
THIS IS WHERE THE SECURITY DOORS
WERE INSTALLED TO KEEP PEOPLE
OUT.
POLICE LATER SAID THE GLASS HAD
BEEN BROKEN OUT OF THESE.
THAT'S APPARENTLY HOW HE GOT
INTO THE SCHOOL WITH THOSE
WEAPONS.
WHAT WE KNOW IS BASED ON POLICE
REPORTS, BY 9:36 WE HAVE THE
FIRST CALLS INTO THE POLICE
STATION SAYING SHOOTING WAS
OCCURRING INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
EVERYBODY IN THE SCHOOL WAS
ALERT
ALERTED TO THE SOUNDS IN THE
SCHOOL.
AND THIS IS ALSO SIGNIFICANT.
BY 9:38, 2 TO 2 1/2 MINUTES
LATER, POLICE WERE SAYING IF NOT
ALL OF THE SHOOTING, THE BULK OF
THE SHOOTING WAS OVER.
A VERY SHORT PERIOD OF TIME IN A
VERY SMALL AREA WHERE WHERE IT
ALL SEEMED TO OCCUR.
WHAT HAPPENED AFTER THAT?
WELL, IT PROGRESSED EVEN FURTHER
BY ABOUT 9:40 IN THE MORNING,
POLICE WERE CALLING FOR
EMERGENCY MEDICAL TECHNICIANS TO
COME THERE, FOR AMBULANCES TO
COME.
A VERY FEW MINUTES LATER, THEY
CALLED FOR A WHOLE LOT MORE
AMBULANCES TO COME.
AND BY 9:50 OR SO IN THE
MORNING, THEY WERE ESSENTIALLY
SAYING THAT THE SCENE WAS
SECURE, THAT THEY HAD A SUSPECT
WHO WAS DOWN, THEY CLEARED THE
BUILDING AND MANY CHILDREN WERE
BEING LED OUT.
AS YOU CAN SEE THIS PHOTOGRAPH
FROM THE NEWTON B.
AND THE SITUATION WAS MORE OR
LESS SECURE.
THERE WAS STILL AN AWFUL LOT OF
WORK TO BE DONE, OBVIOUSLY, BUT
AS YOU CAN SEE, AS WE LOOK AT
THIS TIME LINE, CLOSER AND
CLOSER, IT REALLY IS COMING DOWN
TO A VERY SHORT PERIOD OF TIME,
20 MINUTES OR LESS FROM THE
BEGINNING TO THE END OF THIS IN
TERMS OF PEOPLE REALLY KNOWING
WHAT WAS HAPPENING.
AND NOW HUGE LONG, LONG SEARCH
TO UNDERSTAND WHY IT HAPPENED.
ANDERSON?
>> APPRECIATE THAT.
THE LATEST INFORMATION THAT WE
HAVE.
AND AS I SAID, WE'RE TRYING TO
COLLECT PIECES OF INFORMATION AS
WE GET THEM AND BRING THEM TO
YOU.
I WANT TO SHOW YOU A LIVE
PICTURE RIGHT NOW IN NEWTOWN.
A CANDLE LIGHT VIGIL.
TODAY AND LAST NIGHT.
PEOPLE GATHERING, PEOPLE JUST
WANT TO KIND OF BE TOGETHER.
AND SOMETIMES JUST BE TOGETHER
IN SILENCE, SOMETIMES TALK,
SOMETIMES JUST HUG AND CRY.
WE'VE SEEN ALL OF THAT IN THE
STREETS OF NEWTOWN.
WE ARE GETTING NEW INFORMATION
TONIGHT ABOUT THE FIRST PERSON
THAT WAS KILLED IN NEWTOWN.
THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER, NANCY.
>> IT'S BECOME REALLY A PORTION
OF WHO THIS WOMAN WAS.
THE VINLS I SPOKE TO IN SOME OF
THE NEIGHBORHOODS IN THIS AREA
PAINT A PICTURE OF THIS WOMAN
WHO ATTENDED THESE SORT OF
WEEKLY OR MONTHLY DICE GAMES IN
WHICH SHE WOULD GATHER WITH
RESIDENTS IN THIS COMMUNITY,
WHICH THEY DESCRIBE AS A
TIGHT-KNIT GROUPS WHO WOULD PLAY
THESE DICE GAMES, GARDEN AND
TALK ABOUT LANDSCAPING.
THE JOKE IS THAT THE HOUSE
BEHIND ME WHERE ALL OF THIS
INCIDENT TOOK PLACE IS SET BACK,
AND SHE WOULD TALK ABOUT DOING
THE LANDSCAPING IN THE BACK AND,
YOU KNOW, THE LANDSCAPE IS
REALLY NOTHING PEOPLE WOULD SEE.
IT PAINTS THIS PICTURE OF THIS
WOMAN WHO ATTENDED THESE SORT OF
PARLOR-LIKE GAMES AND YET AT THE
SAME TIME HAD THIS COLLECTION OF
GUNS, SOME OF WHICH WERE VERY
HIGH POWERED GUNS, LIKE THE
BUSHMASTER, SIMILAR TO WHAT
SOLDIERS IN IRAQ AND
AFGHANISTAN, SIMILAR TO THAT
TYPE OF WEAPON.
SO IT DOESN'T QUITE JIVE WITH
THE SCENE THAT THE NEIGHBORS
PAINT OF WHO THIS WOMAN WAS
DURING HER DAY TO DAY
INTERACTIONS WITH THEM.
SOMEONE WHO KEPT TO HERSELF, SHE
MOVED INTO THE AREA ABOUT 1998.
DIVORCED WITH HER HUSBAND YEARS
LATER.
AND HER TWO BOYS GREW UP HERE.
WHAT TRANSPIRED NEXT REALLY LED
TO THIS INCIDENT HAS ONLY RAISED
MORE QUESTIONS.
THAT'S SORT OF THE THING WE FIND
BEING HERE.
THE MORE QUESTIONS WE GET
ANSWERED THE MORE WE HAVE.
AND WHAT BROUGHT THIS TRAGEDY ON
THIS TOWN SUBPOENA NOT REALLY
SOMETHING THAT CAN BE ANSWERED,
IT SEEMS.
>> A LOT OF PEOPLE HAVE A LOT OF
QUESTIONS IN THIS COMMUNITY AND
ELSEWHERE.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY HAD
RECENTLY INSTALLED A NEW
SECURITY SYSTEM.
INCLUDING LOCKING THE DOORS AT
9:00 A.M.
THAT'S AROUND THE TIME THE
GUNMAN WAS ABLE TO FORCE HIS WAY
INTO THE BUILD, BUT THEY HAVEN'T
SAID EXACTLY HOW THEY GOT IN.
A FORMER NASSAU COUNTY NEW YORK
POLICE OFFICER AND DIRECTOR OF
THE ELITE INTELLIGENCE AND
PROTECTION, IS THERE ANY
SECURITY SYSTEM THAT, I MEAN,
PROTECTS SCHOOLS IN THIS WAY?
>> THERE ISN'T ONE THAT'S
DESIGNED TO.
YOU CAN FORT FIE THE DOORS,
UPGRADE THE LOCKS.
ONE I THINK EVERY SCHOOL SHOULD
CONSIDER, EVEN BEFORE THIS
INCIDENT WAS MAKING THESE
CLASSROOMS SAFE ROOMS IN A
SENSE.
BY FORTIFYING THE CLASSROOM
DPOORS, KEEPING THEM LOCKED AT
ALL TIMES AND UPGRADING A LOCK
SYSTEM.
YOU COULD CREATE A SOMEWHAT
SAFER ENVIRONMENT FOR THEM IN AN
INSTANCE LIKE THIS.
IF WE'RE TALKING ABOUT TURNING
OUR CLASSROOMS INTO SOMEWHAT
FORTIFIED --
>> THAT'S WHAT IT SOUNDS LIKE.
>> THAT'S A KNEE-JERK REACTION.
MAYBE WE SHOULD PUT ARMED POLICE
OFFICERS IN ALL OUR SCHOOLS.
THAT'S JUST NOT FEASIBLE.
I DON'T THINK THAT'S AN
EMOTIONALLY HEALTHY ENVIRONMENT
FOR KIDS TO LEARN IN EITHER.
>> A LOT OF SCHOOLS WERE
DESIGNED TO BE OPEN PLACES, OPEN
FOR TEACHERS, OPEN FOR STUDENTS.
AND NOW THEY'RE STARTING TO HAVE
TO RETHINK THAT, TO NOT HAVE THE
ARCHITECTURE OF THE SCHOOL BE
QUITE SO OPEN.
>> UNFORTUNATELY, WE'RE
REGRESSING IS WHAT THIS COMES
DOWN TO.
THESE ARE INSTITUTIONS WHERE WE
LEARN, WHERE WE ABSORB
KNOWLEDGE, WHERE WE'RE SUPPOSED
TO BE SAFE IN DOING THAT OR
EXPERIENCING THAT PROCESS.
AND WHAT WE'RE LOOKING AT IS THE
DETERIORATI
DETERIORATION OF THE CULTURE.
THIS IS A DIFFERENT FORMAT OF
THE GUN.
WE HAVE ISSUES HERE ABOUT
FAILING TO SAFEGUARD THESE
WEAPONS.
>> THE POLICE SAY A WOMAN WHO
WAS WOUNDED AT THE SCHOOL IS
GOING TO BE INSTRUMENTAL TO THE
INVESTIGATION.
AT THIS POINT, WHAT ARE POLICE
DOING?
>> THEY'RE CONTINUING THIS
INVESTIGATION.
YOU KNOW, THEY'RE GATHERING
EVIDENCE.
THEY'RE TRYING TO DETERMINE
CONCLUSIVELY IF HE ACTED A I
LOAN.
THEY HAVE TO DO THAT.
THEY'RE PREPARING FOR POSSIBLY
ANY FUTURE COURT CASES.
THEY'RE DOING A LOT OF DIFFERENT
THINGS.
THEY'RE TRYING TO FIND OUT
EXACTLY WHAT TRANSPIRED IN THAT
CLASSROOM.
DID HE LEAVE US ANY MESSAGES,
VERBALLY, WRITTEN, COMPUTER, SO
ON AND SO FORTH.
THEY'RE TRYING TO VET THIS
ENTIRE INCIDENT TO FIND OUT WHAT
MAY HAVE PRECIPITATED IT.
BEYOND THE PARE
>> BEYOND THE PARENTS, I THINK
OF THE FIRST RESPONDERS.
THIS IS A CRIME SCENE.
YOU KNOW, I SHUTTER TO THINK OF
WHAT THAT CRIME SCENE LOOKS
LIKE.
BUT THEY HAVE TO CATALOG IT.
THEY HAVE TO DOCUMENT IT.
>> YEAH.
I MEAN, YOU HAVE TO REALIZE THE
EMOTIONALLY, THE TOLL THIS TAKES
ON LAW ENFORCEMENT AGENCY.
AS A RULE, WE DEAL WITH THE
UNDERBELLY OF OUR SOCIETY AND
PART OF OUR EXERCISE IS TO
INSULATE THE GENERAL PUBLIC FROM
HOW DARK THIS GETS.
THESE MEN OR WOMEN WENT INTO
THIS ROOM LOOKING AT THESE
CHILDREN THAT WERE BASICALLY
SLAUGHTERED, SHOT MULTIPLE
TIMES.
THESE ARE BABIES.
OUR BABIES.
>> I APPRECIATE YOU BEING WITH
US.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I'M SORRY IT'S UNDER THESE
CIRCUMSTANCES.
WE HAVE A LOT AHEAD.
WE'RE TRYING TO GET AS MUCH
INFORMATION AS WE CAN.
WE WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A SHORT
BREAK.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S SIMPLE PHYSICS...
A BODY AT REST
TENDS TO STAY AT REST...
WHILE A BODY IN MOTION
TENDS TO STAY IN MOTION.
STAYING ACTIVE CAN ACTUALLY
EASE ARTHRITIS SYMPTOMS.
BUT IF YOU HAVE ARTHRITIS,
STAYING ACTIVE
CAN BE DIFFICULT.
PRESCRIPTION CELEBREX
CAN HELP RELIEVE ARTHRITIS PAIN
SO YOUR BODY
CAN STAY IN MOTION.
BECAUSE JUST ONE
200MG CELEBREX A DAY
CAN PROVIDE 24 HOUR RELIEF
FOR MANY WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND INFLAMMATION.
PLUS, IN CLINICAL STUDIES,
CELEBREX IS PROVEN TO IMPROVE
DAILY PHYSICAL FUNCTION
SO MOVING IS EASIER.
CELEBREX CAN BE TAKEN WITH
OR WITHOUT FOOD.
AND IT'S NOT A NARCOTIC.
YOU AND YOUR DOCTOR
SHOULD BALANCE THE BENEFITS
WITH THE RISKS.
ALL PRESCRIPTION NSAIDS,
LIKE CELEBREX, IBUPROFEN,
NAPROXEN, AND MELOXICAM
HAVE THE SAME
CARDIOVASCULAR WARNING.
THEY ALL MAY INCREASE
THE CHANCE
OF HEART ATTACK OR STROKE,
WHICH CAN LEAD TO DEATH.
THIS CHANCE INCREASES
IF YOU HAVE HEART DISEASE
OR RISK FACTORS
SUCH AS HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE
OR WHEN NSAIDS ARE TAKEN
FOR LONG PERIODS.
NSAIDS, INCLUDING CELEBREX,
INCREASE THE CHANCE OF SERIOUS
SKIN OR ALLERGIC REACTIONS
OR STOMACH AND INTESTINE
PROBLEMS,
SUCH AS BLEEDING AND ULCERS,
WHICH CAN OCCUR WITHOUT WARNING
AND MAY CAUSE DEATH.
PATIENTS ALSO TAKING ASPIRIN
AND THE ELDERLY
ARE AT INCREASED RISK FOR
STOMACH BLEEDING AND ULCERS.
DO NOT TAKE CELEBREX IF YOU'VE
HAD AN ASTHMA ATTACK, HIVES,
OR OTHER ALLERGIES TO ASPIRIN,
NSAIDS OR SULFONAMIDES.
GET HELP RIGHT AWAY IF YOU HAVE
SWELLING OF THE FACE OR THROAT,
OR TROUBLE BREATHING.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
YOUR MEDICAL HISTORY
AND FIND AN ARTHRITIS TREATMENT
FOR YOU.
VISIT CELEBREX.COM AND ASK
YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT CELEBREX.
FOR A BODY IN MOTION.
>> THIS IS A VERY, VERY TRAGIC.
CERTAINLY OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN
FOR THE FAMILIES HERE.
>> ABOUT 9:30, 9:40, WE HEARD
NOISES AND THE ANNOUNCEMENT
SYSTEM WAS SO ON.
IT DIDN'T GO OFF SO YOU COULD
HEAR WHAT SOUNDED LIKE POPS,
GUNSHOTS.
>> HER TEACHER MANAGED TO TAKE
TWO CHILDREN OUT OF THE HALL
WAY, PULL THEM INTO THE
CLASSROOM, LOCKED THE DOOR AND
MOVE EVERYBODY OVER TO THE OTHER
SIDE OF THE ROOM.
>> WE JUST TOLD A LITTLE BOY
ABOUT HIS SISTER NOW.
JUST TO SEE HIS HEART, WHO AM I
GOING TO PLAY WITH, HE SAID?
>> WHEN YOUR FIRST GRADER GOES
TO BED AND SAYS MOMMY, ANYONE
FROM MY CLASS LAST YEAR, ARE
THEY ALL OKAY?
AND YOU LOOK AT THEM AND SAY I'M
NOT REALLY SURE.
>> YOU CAN NEVER BE PREPARED FOR
THIS KIND OF INCIDENT.
WHAT HAS HAPPENED, WHAT HAS
TRANSPIRED AT THAT SCHOOL
BUILDING WILL LEAVE A MARK ON
THIS COMMUNITY AND EVERY FAMILY
IMPACTED.
>> SOME WANT TO GRIEVE IN
SILENCE, OTHERS WANT TO TALK,
TALK TO THE MEDIA, LOVED ONES,
TALK TO EVEN STRANGERS ON
STREETS.
THERE'S A LOT OF PEOPLE GATHERED
OUT TONIGHT, EVEN THOUGH IT'S
VERY COLD.
YOU WERE ACTUALLY AT ONE OF THE
PLACES, A KIND OF GATHERING
POINT FOR PEOPLE WHO WANT TO
TALK TO COUNSELORS.
AND WHAT WAS THAT LIKE?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, I DIDN'T KNOW
WHAT TO EXPECT.
BECAUSE, YOU KNOW, IT WAS SO RAW
STILL.
I DIDN'T KNOW IF PEOPLE WERE
GOING TO GO TO THIS CENTER.
WHEN WE GOT THERE, THERE WAS
LITERALLY 100 CARS IN THE
PARKING LOT.
AND OUT OF RESPECT FOR PEOPLE'S
PRIVACY, WE WEREN'T FILMING
ANYTHING.
BUT PEOPLE WERE WALKING OUT WITH
CHILDREN.
PROBABLY CHILDREN FROM THE
SCHOOL.
A LOT OF PARENTS WALKING WITH
THEM INTO THE SCHOOL AND THERE
WERE PSYCHIATRIST,
PSYCHOLOGISTS, CHILDREN'S
COUNSELORS IN THE SCHOOL.
I THINK WHAT WAS REALLY STRIKING
IS PEOPLE WERE GOING IN AND
STAYING IN FOR A LONG TIME.
I MEAN, THIS WAS A, I'M SURE,
GRIEVING, BUT ALSO HEALING GOING
ON.
AND ALSO THIS WHOLE IDEA THAT
THE COMMUNITY WAS SORT OF AN
INDIVIDUAL.
MEANING THAT, YOU KNOW, YOU SAW
THAT SOMEONE ELSE WAS GOING
THROUGH THE SAME THING YOU WERE.
AND PEOPLE WERE BEING COMFORTED
BY THAT IN SOME WAYS.
>> IT'S INTERESTING, I WAS
TALKING TO MY MOM WHO LOST A
SON, MY BROTHER.
AND SHE WAS SAYING FOR HER, IT
HELPED TO TALK ABOUT IT.
AND I'VE HEARD THAT FROM A LOT
OF PEOPLE HERE, THAT IT HELPS TO
TALK.
YET OTHER PEOPLE AREN'T READY TO
TALK ABOUT IT OR CAN'T TALK
ABOUT IT.
>> YEAH.
I THINK THE TIMING SEEMS TO BE
DIFFERENT FOR DIFFERENT PEOPLE.
WHICH IS WHY I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT
TO EXPECT.
BUT IT SEEMS LIKE THIS COMMUNITY
FOR THE MOST PART IS READY TO
TALK.
I MEAN, THIS IS OBVIOUSLY A
SMALL SAMPLE SIZE, BUT PEOPLE
ARE TALKING ABOUT IT.
AND THE FEELING OF ISOLATION,
THINKING THAT I'M GOING THROUGH
THIS ALONE, THAT NO ONE QUITE
UNDERSTANDS WHAT THIS HAS DONE
TO ME CAN BE QUITE PAINFUL AND
QUITE DAMAGING LONG TERM AS
WELL.
SO IF YOU SEE OTHER PEOPLE GOING
THROUGH IT, AND EVEN JUST BEING
THERE IN THE CRISIS CENTER WITH
OTHER PEOPLE, I THINK IS ASSUMED
TO BE SOMEWHAT THERAPEUTIC.
>> OTHER PATIENTS AROUND THE
WORLD ARE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
HOW TO TALK TO THEIR KIDS ABOUT
IT.
I TALKED TO PARENTS LAST NIGHT
WHOSE KIDS WERE IN THE SCHOOL
AND THANKFULLY SURVIVED, THEY
WERE WAITING FOR THEIR CHILDREN
TO KIND OF BRING IT UP TO THEM.
THAT'S WIN WAY TO DO IT.
>> OBVIOUSLY THE CHILDREN IN THE
SCHOOL KNOW.
OTHER CHILDREN IN THE COMMUNITY
KNOW, EVEN IF THEY HADN'T BEEN
WATCHING TELEVISION, IN TODAY'S
DAY AND AGE.
THE THING THAT KEEPS COMING BACK
IS THEY SORT OF DIRECT THE
CONVERSATION.
YOU SORT OF GET YOUR OWN
FEELINGS IN CHECK FIRST AS AN
ADULT OR AS A PARENT, AND THEN
YOU FILL IN DETAILS AS
APPROPRIATE.
AS AGE FROEPT.
-- APPROPRIATE.
LEAVING OUT GRAPHIC DETAILS.
BUT THIS WHOLE IDEA THAT YOU
DON'T WANT TO BE FALSE OR YOU
WANT TO BE VERY TRANSPARENT.
I HAD THIS CONVERSATION WITH MY
DAUGHTER.
THE FIRST THING SHE ASKED ME,
SHE STARTED ASKING ME ABOUT SOME
OF THE NAMES OF THE CHILDREN.
I THINK THAT'S INTERESTING.
THEY IMMEDIATELY WANT TO
HUMANIZE THIS.
IT WAS A TOUGH CONVERSATION TO
HAVE.
SHE WANTED TO KNOW IF HER SCHOOL
WAS GOING TO BE SAFE. I HAVE TO
SAY LOOK, DADDY'S SCHOOL NEVER
HAD THIS HAPPEN TO THEM.
MOMMY'S SCHOOL NEVER HAPPENED TO
HER.
WE DO THE BEST WE CAN TO KEEP
YOU SAFE.CONVERSATIONS.
>> YESTERDAY, THERE WERE REPORTS
THE SHOOTER'S BROTHER HAD SAID
THAT HE HAD A PERSONALITY
DISORDER.
MAYBE HE WAS SOMEWHERE ON
AUTOTICHL SPECTRUM.
THOSE ARE TWO SEPARATE THINGS.
AND I HAD NEVER HEARD OF AUTISM
BEING ANYTHING TO DO WITH A
PREPLANNED ACT OF VIOLENCE.
I THINK A LOT OF PEOPLE WHO ARE
CHILDREN WHO ARE UH TISIC ARE
UPSET THAT THE WORD AUTISM IS
EVEN BEING MENTIONED IN
RELATIONSHIP TO THIS.
>> I'M GLAD YOU SAID IT BECAUSE,
YOU KNOW, I LOOKED THIS UP AGAIN
TODAY.
I TALKED TO SOME OF MY EXPERTS I
TALK TO IN THIS SORT OF THING.
THERE WAS NO EVIDENCE AT ALL,
THERE'S NO EVIDENCE TO SUGGEST
THAT SOMEONE ON THE AUTISM
SPECTRUM IS -- IT COULD BE
PREPLANNED VIOLENCE.
AND PEOPLE HAVE VIOLENT
OUTBURSTS SOMETIMES, REACTIVE
VIOLENCE.
BUT PREPLANNED VIOLENCE JUST
ISN'T SOMETHING THAT'S
ASSOCIATED WITH THIS.
I TRIED TO MAKE THAT CLEAR ALL
DAY.
I HEARD THAT SAME THING.
THERE'S JUST NO EVIDENCE OF THAT
WHATSOEVER.
ALSO THIS WHOLE NOTION, YOU
KNOW, ASBERGER,
WHATEVER, THAT'S SOMETHING
THAT'S A NEURODEVELOPMENTAL
DISORDER.
IT'S NOT A PERSONALITY DISORDER.
THE IT'S NOT A MENTAL ILLNESS.
IT'S A NEURODEVELOPAL DISORDER.
>> I HOPE THAT CLARIFIES IT.
THAT'S SOMETHING WE WILL TRY TO
REPEAT AS MUCH AS WE CAN.
WE DON'T WANT TO GIVE ANYONE A
FALSE IMPRESSION ABOUT KIDS WITH
AUTISM.
AND AGAIN, THERE'S STILL SO MUCH
WE DON'T KNOW ABOUT THE MENTAL
STATE OF THIS GUNMAN.
SANJAY, APPRECIATE IT.
GOING TO HAVE MORE WITH SANJAY
IN THE 10:00 HOUR, ANOTHER
EDITION OF "360."
THERE'S STILL A LOT OF
INFORMATION WE'RE TRYING TO GO
THROUGH.
ALSO GETTING NEW INFORMATION.
ACTUALLY, I DO WANT TO ASK YOU
BRIEFLY ABOUT -- THERE'S SOME
INFORMATION ON SECRETARY OF
STATE HILLARY CLINTON, THAT SHE
FELL AND POSSIBLY HAD A
CONCUSSION.
WHAT HAVE YOU HEARD?
>> EARLIER THIS WEEK, SHE WAS
DEALING WITH A STOMACH VIRUS.
SHE FAINTED.
WHEN SHE FAINTED SHE HIT HER
HEAD.
JUST TODAY NOW, THEY SAY SHE
LIKELY HAD A CONCUSSION.
SO IT TOOK A FEW DAYS TO
ACTUALLY CLARIFY THAT AND MAKE
THAT DIAGNOSIS.
SO THE DOCTORS HAVE RECOMMENDED
THAT IT'S OKAY FOR HER TO BE AT
HOME.
THAT'S VERY IMPORTANT.
I THINK THEY HAVE A LOW
THRESHOLD FOR HER BEING IN THE
HOSPITAL.
THEY'RE COMFORTABLE WITH HER
BEING AT HOME, BUT ALSO SAYING
NO STRENUOUS ACTIVITY AND REALLY
NO WORK.
WITH A CONCUSSION, YOU WANT TO
MAKE SURE THAT THE BRAIN IS SORT
OF RESTED.
LITERALLY THEY SAY DON'T WATCH
TELEVISION, DON'T READ A
NEWSPAPER, LET THE BRAIN SORT OF
REST.
I' NOT SURE SHE'S SOMEONE
CAPABLE OF DOING THAT, FRANKLY,
BUT THAT'S WHAT THEY'RE
RECOMMENDING.
>> APPRECIATE THAT.
MORE FROM NEWTOWN AHEAD.
JAYMI'S CHRISTMAS SHOPPING
AND WAS LOOKING FOR
GIFTS AT BEST BUY.
YOU WANNA SEE IF WALMART HAS
SIMILAR GIFTS FOR LESS?
YEAH.
LET'S GO.
SAMSUNG GALAXY S3 --
OVER FIFTY DOLLARS LESS
THAN BEST BUY!
WOW! FIFTY BUCKS!
YEAH!
THAT'S A PAIR OF SHOES.
SEE FOR YOURSELF IF YOU COULD
SAVE ON THE GIFTS YOU WANT.
WALMART.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
>> ANOTHER MAZ KILLINGS IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, HAVE
PROMPTED SOME TO WANT TO TURN
SCHOOLS INTO FORTRESSES.
WE TALKED ABOUT THAT A SHORT
TIME AGO.
EVEN THOUGH IT MAY SOUND DESI
DESIRAB
DESIRABLE, IT'S NOT REALLY
POSSIBLE.
HOW CAN WE ALL PROTECT OUR
CHILDREN, NOT ONLY AT HOME IN
COMMUNITIES BUT AT SCHOOL.
WHAT DO WE GIVE UP TO GAIN A
MEASURE OF SECURITY, KNOWING NO
STRATEGY CAN ABC CHUTLY
GUARANTEE OUR KIDS WILL BE SAFE
IN SCHOOL.
>> MICHAEL BLOW HAS SOME IDEAS
ON HOW TO AVOID MAS CASUALTIES
IF A GUNMAN IS INSIDE YOUR
SCHOOL.
HOW DO YOU RESPOND IF THERE'S
KIDS ALL AROUND?
>> THAT'S WHERE THE TRAINING
COMINGS IN.
>> BLOW IS THE HEAD OF SECURITY.
HE HAD TO ONCE LOCK DOWN A
SCHOOL.
HE TOOK US THROUGH AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL THAT OFFICIALS WANT TO
NAME, SHOWED USZ WHAT TO DO IF
THE NIGHTMARE UNFOLDS.
>> EXITS ARE KEY.
YOU HAVE TO FIND THE NEAREST
ONE?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
AND IT'S IMPORTANT TO BE
FAMILIAR WITH THE BUILDING.
THAT'S WHY AGAIN WE ENCOURAGE
JUST LITTLE THINGS, JUST A
BUILDING FAMILIARIZATION, JUST
WALKING THE OUTSIDE OF THE
BUILDING SO YOU KNOW IF YOU
LEAVE THIS PARTICULAR DOOR IF IT
COMES TO A CREEK OR A PARKING
LOT OR A BUSY INTERSECTION.
>> ADULTS AND STUDENTS, HE SAYS
HAVE TO HAVE THAT EXIT
AWARENESS, BUT IF YOU'RE STUCK
INSIDE, MICHAEL BLOW SAYS WHILE
BATHROOMS MAY BE A TEMPTING
PLACE TO HIDE FIRST, NOT A GOOD
IDEA.
A CONFINED SPACE AND USUALLY NO
WAY OUT.
COURTYARDS HE SAYS ARE EQUALLY
TEMPTING BUT ALSO NOT THE BEST
PLACES BECAUSE THEY'RE OFTEN
ENCLOSED.
>> THIS IS A CLASSROOM, WE HEARD
SHOT, WE DON'T KNOW WHERE HE IS,
WHAT DO WE DO?
DO WE LOCK AND TURN LIGHTS OFF,
CLOSE WINDOWS?
>> CERTAINLY THERE ARE A HOST OF
THINGS THAT WE WOULD DO IN AN
ENERGY.
THAT WOULD INCLUDE LOCKING
DOORS, TO MAKE SURE THAT WE ARE
ABLE TO FORTIFY THAT ENTRANCE
WAY AS BEST AS WE CAN.
AGAIN, IF THERE ARE NO SAFE
ALTERNATIVES FOR EVACUATING THE
BUILDING.
AND THAT WAY IF SOMEONE WAS TO
WALK BY THE ROOM, THEY WOULDN'T
HAVE AN EASY PICTURE OF ANYONE
THAT IS IN THE ROOM.
>> ADULTS IN THE ROOM, HE SAYS,
SHOULD TALK THE KIDS THROUGH IT
AS CALMLY AS POSSIBLE.
>> WHAT ABOUT LARGE ROOMS LIKE
GYMS?
GO IN?
AVOID IT?
>> THERE'S NOT A LOT OF PLACES
TO CONCEAL YOURSELVES AS YOU SEE
THERE.
BUT THERE'S A WAY TO GET TO THE
OTHER SIDE OF THE BUILDING.
>> WE WANT TO ADD ANOTHER VOICE
TO THE CONVERSATION ABOUT
SAFETY.
HECTOR GARCIA HAS ENDEVOTED MUCH
OF HIS PROFESSIONAL LIFE AS A
FORMER SCHOOL POLICE KMEEF.
HE JOINS ME NOW FROM WEST PALM
BEACH, FLORIDA.
I APPRECIATE YOU BEING WITH US.
WE MADE OBVIOUSLY STRIDES SINCE
THE COLUMBINE SCHOOL SHOOTING
BACK IN '99.
BUT WHERE ARE WE NOW AND WHAT
MORE DO YOU THINK NEEDS TO BE
DONE?
>> FIRST OF ALL, THANK YOU,
ANDERSON, FOR HAVING ME.
ONE OF THE THINGS THAT I WOULD
ADVOCATE FOR IS ONCE AGAIN A
RESURGENCE OF THE GRANTS THAT
WERE FRO PROVIDED BY A FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT THAT EFFECTUATED SO
MANY OF THESE TRAINING SESSIONS
FOR OUR SCHOOLCHILDREN AND STAFF
MEMBERS THAT THEY PERFORMED SO
ADMIRABLY DURING THESE TRAGIC
TIMES AS A RESULT OF THAT
TRAINING THAT WAS ADMINISTERED
UNDER GRANT PROGRAMS.
ANYTHING, OTHER GRANT PROGRAMS,
PUTTING POLICE OFFICERS IN
SCHOOLS WHERE THEY CAN ADVOCATE
ALSO AND BE PROTECTORS OF
SCHOOLS HAVE FALLEN ON TO BUDGET
CUTS AS WELL.
WE WOULD LIKE TO SEE THAT COME
BACK INTO EFFECT.
IN ADDITION THERE HAVE BEEN MANY
STUDIES GRANTED BY THE U.S.
SECRET SERVICE.
THERE ARE MANY ADVOCACY GROUP, A
SAFETY ADVOCACY COUNCIL,
NATIONAL SERASSOCIATION OF SCHO
LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICERS WHO ALL
CAME TOGETHER AND DREW UPON THE
BEST PRACTICES AND THE LESSONS
LEARNED AND DEVELOPED MANY OF
THESE PLANS.
WE WOULD LIKE TO SEE A
RESURGENCE OF THAT AGAIN SO WE
CAN HONE WHAT WE HAVE NOW AND
MAKE IT EVEN BETTER BECAUSE THAT
WAS SOMETHING THAT WAS VITAL IN
THIS TRAGEDY.
>> I THINK IT'S A GOOD POINT YOU
RAISED IN THE TRAINING.
I WAS AMAZED, THE TEACHERS I
TALKED TO, JUST HOW THEY HAD
DRILLED FOR SOME SORT OF AN
EVENT, WHETHER IT WAS LIKE THIS
OR SOME SORT OF EMERGENCY EVENT.
THEY GOT THE KIDS INTO THE
CORNERS.
IN ONE CASE, THE TEACHERS SAT
THE KIDS DOWN AND READ TO THEM
TO KIND OF KEEP THEM CALM AND
CONTINUED TO READ ALL THE WAY
THROUGH THIS UNTIL S.W.A.T. TEAM
MEMBERS KNOCKED ON THE DOOR AND
TOLD EVERYBODY IT WAS OKAY TO
COME OUT.
HOW WIDESPREAD IS THAT KIND OF
STRAINING IN SCHOOLS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY.
>> WELL, ANDERSON, THIS TRAINING
IS NOW MANDATORY IN SO MANY
STATES.
AND I BELIEVE THAT IT IS
WIDESPREAD THROUGHOUT THE
COUNTRY.
NOW, THE FREQUENCY OF THE
TRAINING IS CRITICAL.
THE LARGER SCHOOL DISTRICTS ARE
GOING TO DO MORE TRAINING AND
MORE DRILLS AND THEREFORE BE
BETTER PREPARED.
I QUESTION THOSE PRIVATE
SCHOOLS, THOSE PRIVATE
INSTITUTIONS, MAYBE THE SMALLER
ONES THAT ARE NOT REALLY FOC
FOCUSING ON THIS AS MUCH TO
REALLY STEP UP TO THE PLATE.
AND ALSO COME TO THE SAME LEVELS
OF FREQUENCY OF TRAINING AND
DRILLING.
AND OF ALSO REVIEWING, AS THE
EXPERTS SAID EARLIER, THOSE EXIT
PLANS.
HAVE THINGS CHANGED AROUND THEIR
NEIGHBORHOODS?
YOU HAVE TO CONTINUE TO LIVE
THIS -- MAKE IT A LIVING
DOCUMENT AND CONTINUE TO EVOLVE
AND TO MASTER THAT CRISIS PLAN
AND DRILL IT DOWN, DRILL IT
DOWN, ALL THE WAY TO THE
TEACHERS AND EVEN THE PARENTS
WHO MAY BE THERE.
>> I APPRECIATE YOUR EXPERTISE.
THE TRAGEDY IN THIS COMMUNITY
HAS TOUCHED PEOPLE AROUND THE
WORLD.
THIS HAS MADE THE FRONT PAGE OF
PAPERS ALL AROUND THE WORLD.
IN ENGLAND, SEVERAL SOCCER TEAMS
WORE BLACK ARM BANDS TO HONOR
THE VICTIMS.
ONE TEAM NOTED THE TRIBUTE WAS
AT THE REQUEST OF THE PLAYER
THEMSELVES.
TAKE A LOOK AT THESE PICTURES
FROM BRAZIL.
BLACK CROSSES FOR EACH OF THE
VICTIMS IN RIO DEJANEIRO.
MANY NEWSPAPERS COMPARED IT TO
TRAGEDIES THAT UNFOLDED ON THEIR
OWN SOIL.
AND SOME SPECULATED WHETHER THIS
COULD BE THE EVENT THAT SHIFTS
AMERICA'S ATTITUDE ON GUN
CONTROL, EITHER BECAUSE OF THE
AGE OF THE VICTIMS OR BECAUSE
AMERICANS CAN ONLY TOLERATE SO
MANY SENSELESS DEATHS FROM GUN
VIOLENCE.
BE RIGHT BACK.
>>> THIS IS CNN.
THIS EVENING, A COMMUNITY IN
SHOCK AND MOURNING, JUST ONE DAY
AFTER AN HORRIFIC EVENT THAT