THOSE THAT ARE LOST ARE YOUNG
CHILDREN.
>> PEOPLE'S CHILDREN, BROTHERS
AND SISTERS WERE TAKEN FROM
THEM.
PEOPLE'S SPOUSES.
THE TEACHERS AND D MAIN STRAIGHT
-- ADMINISTRATORS WERE TAKEN.
>> I HAVE TO COMMEND THE STAFF
OF THE SCHOOL WHO WERE THERE FOR
THE CHILDREN WHICH IS WHAT
TEACHERS ARE ALL ABOUT.
IT WAS MOST OBVIOUS TODAY.
MOST OBVIOUS TODAY WHAT THEY
REALLY ARE ABOUT AS TEACHERS.
TO ALL OF THEM, I SAY THANKS ON
BEHALF OF ALL OF US.
>>> GOOD EVENING.
BREAKING NEWS.
I'M ASHLEIGH BANFIELD IN FOR
ERIN BURNETT TONIGHT.
I CAN TELL YOU HIS MOTHER NANCY
LANZA WAS FOUND DEAD AT THE
FAMILY HOME HERE IN NEWTOWN, AS
WELL.
SHE HAD BEEN A TEACHER AT THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE SCHOOL'S PRINCIPAL DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG
WAS AMONG THOSE KILLED AND
TONIGHT A FRIEND REMEMBERED HER
AS "QUOTE, THE KIND OF PERSON
YOU WOULD WANT TO BE EDUCATING
YOUR KIDS.
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST MARY
SHERLOCK WAS ALSO KILGED.
THIS AFTERNOON AFTERNOON THE
BROTHER, RYAN LANZA WAS TAKEN IN
FOR QUESTIONING BY POLICE AND HE
WAS HANDCUFFED.
OFFICIALS DID NOT LABEL HIM A
SUSPECT.
THE GUNMAN'S FATHER WAS ALSO
QUESTIONED IN RELATION TO WHAT
HAPPENED HERE TODAY.
TONIGHT, A NATION IN MOURNING.
CANDLE LIGHT VIGILS WERE HELD IN
NEWTOWN AND ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
THERE WAS ONE JUST OUTSIDE OF
THE WHITE HOUSE IN WASHINGTON,
D.C.
EARLIER TODAY, PRESIDENT OBAMA
ORDERED FLAGS TO BE FLOWN AT
HALF STAFF NATIONWIDE IN TRIBUTE
TO THE VICTIMS OF THIS TERRIBLE
TRAGEDY.
IN AN EMOTIONAL ADDRESS, HE SAID
THIS TO THE NATION.
>> I KNOW THERE'S NOT A PARENT
IN AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
>> Reporter: THE PRESIDENT,
INCREDIBLY EMOTIONAL AS HE
.
A MASSER OF INNOCENT TINY
CHILDREN AND THE WEAPONS USED
NOTHING SHORT OF TERRIFYING.
OUR SUSAN CANDIOTTI HAS BEEN
FOLLOWING THE DEVELOPMENTS
TODAY.
THREE DIFFERENT WEAPONS FOUND IN
DIFFERENT PLACES, VERY, VERY
DANGEROUS WEAPONS.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
TWO OF THE WEAPONS WERE FOUND ON
THE SHOOTER HIMSELF N THE
CLASSROOM WHERE HE WAS FOUND
DEAD.
ONE OF THEM IS A GLOCK AND THE
OTHER IS A CIGGING SAUER.
BOTH HANDGUNS.
A THIRD WEAPON WAS FOUND IN A
CAR IN A VEHICLE, MAY HAVE BEEN
HIS OUTSIDE OF THE SCHOOL.
>> IS THAT THE VEHICLE THAT HAD
BEEN PARKED ERRATICALLY AND
ROPED OFF WITH THE CRIME TAPE?
>> EXACTLY.
THEY WERE PAYING A LOT OF
ATTENTION, CLOSELY EXAMINING THE
CAR.
THE THIRD IS A SEMIAUTOMATIC
KNOWN AS A BUSHMASTER .223.
WE UNDERSTAND ALL OF THE WEAPONS
BELONGED TO HIS MOTHER.
HIS MOTHER WAS A SCHOOLTEACHER
AT THE SCHOOL.
THEY WERE REGISTERED IN THE
STATE OF CONNECTICUT, AS WELL.
TRYING TO PIECE THIS ALL
TOGETHER, WHY DID SHE HAVE THOSE
GUNS?
HOW DID HE GET THEM?
>> JUST ONE AREA I KNOW WILL BE
A HUGE TOPIC OF CONVERSATION FOR
DAYS AND MONTHS TO COME.
ANOTHER BIG QUESTION FOR SO MANY
THE NAMES OF THESE CHILDREN.
THERE ARE 20 CHILDREN WHO DIED.
THERE ARE SIX ADULTS WHO DIED IN
THE SCHOOL.
THERE'S NANCY, THE MOTHER WHO
DIED IN HER RESIDENCE.
WHEN WILL WE FIND OUT THE
OFFICIAL IDENTITIES OF THESE
VICTIMS?
>> RIGHT.
LAW ENFORCEMENT AUTHORITIES ARE
TELLING US IT WILL BE TOMORROW
MORNING.
THEY EXPECT TO BE RELEASING THE
IDENTITIES.
THEY HAVE BEEN WORKING
DILIGENTLY TO CHECK, DOUBLE
CHECK AND TRIPLE CHECK THAT THEY
HAVE ALL OF THE RIGHT PEOPLE AND
OBVIOUSLY THAT EVERYONE, MEMBERS
OF THE FAMILY HAVE BEEN
NOTIFIED.
EXPECT TO HEAR THAT IN THE
MORNING.
>> SO SAD TO SEE BY EXCLUSION
THEY HAVE MADE THE IDENTITIES
OBVIOUS TO FAMILY MEMBERS WHO
DID NOT GET REUNITED WITH THEIR
CHILDREN BUT THE POSITIVE I.D.s
THEY TALKED ABOUT A FORENSIC
PROJECT THEY WILL BE WORKING ON
WHERE THE CHILDREN'S BODIES ARE.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
WE APPRECIATE IT.
>> YOU ARE WELCOME.
>> OUR DREW GRIFFIN HAS BEEN
BUSY WORKING ON WHATEVER
INFORMATION WE CAN FIND ON THIS
PERSON, THE SHOOTER.
ADAM LANZA.
WHAT HAVE YOU FOUND OUT, DREW?
>> HAVING COVERED SO MANY OF
THESE, IN FACT WITH SUSAN
CANDIOTTI IT IS PLAYING OUT
ALMOST IN A SICKENING ROUTINE A
SHOOTER WITH A POSSIBLE MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUE WITH FAMILY,
POSSIBLY TRYING TO DEAL WITH
THOSE ISSUES, SMAG SNAPS,
POWERFUL GUNS EASILY ACCESSED
AND YOU HAVE AN OUTBURST OF
VIOLENCE.
THE CASE IS PLAYING OUT JUST
EXACTLY IN THAT ORDER.
HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW THE
20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER HAD AN OLDER
BROTHER.
THAT BROTHER REPORTEDLY TOLD ABC
NEWS, THE BROTHER HAD A
PERSONALITY DISORDER.
HE ALSO MENTIONED HIS BROTHER
HAD AUTISM OR WAS AUTISTIC.
CNN HEARD THE SAME FLFGS A MAN
WHO CALLED HIMSELF A FRIEND IN
NEWTOWN WHERE THE SHOOTER LIVED.
SO WE ARE SEEING A BASE FOR SOME
MENTAL HEALTH QUESTIONS BEING
RAISED.
>> ONE MORE QUESTION.
AND DREW, NIQUICKLY, IS ANYONE
TALKING ABOUT WARNING SIGNS?
>> OTHER THAN WHAT I JUST
MENTIONED NOT YET.
I EXPECT WE WILL SEE MORE DETAIL
ON THAT.
RIGHT NOW, ALSO SOMEWHAT
STANDARD IN THESE CASES, YOU
WILL FIND PEOPLE SHOCKED THIS
PERSON COULD HAVE BEEN INVOLVED
IN ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
LISTEN TO WHAT WE HEARD FROM A
FORMER CLASSMATE AND A FORMER
SCHOOL BUS DRIVER WHO KNEW THIS
20-YEAR-OLD.
>> JUST A KID.
>> NEVER ANTI-SOCIAL?
>> NO.
NO.
>> TROUBLEMAKER.
>> NO.
DEFINITELY NOT.
>> NOTICEABLE?
DID HE JUST BLEND IN TO THE
BACKGROUND?
>> YEAH.
NOTHING THAT WOULD WARRANT ANY
OF THIS.
>> THEY ARE SAYING HE WENT AFTER
HIS MOM AND HER CLASS OF KIDS.
CAN YOU WRAP YOUR HEAD AROUND
THAT?
>> NO.
I CANNOT.
I DON'T KNOW ANYONE WHO WOULD DO
ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
>> SO YOUR GENERAL SENSE IS
WHAT?
>> THIS IS UNSPEAKABLE.
I FIRST HEARD ABOUT IT.
I'M STILL IN SHOCK.
GIVE ME A MOMENT.
I WANT TO GO.
I'M GOING TO GO WALK AROUND.
>> HE WAS A NICE KID, VERY
POLITE.
SHE RAISED VERY NICE BOYS TO ME.
THAT'S WHY I THINK IT IS A SHOCK
TO EVEN THOUGH THEM AND REALIZE
WHO THEY ARE AND WHAT HE DID.
YOU CAN'T UNDERSTAND WHAT
HAPPENED THAT HE SNAPPED, HAVE
WHAT YOU AND HE TOOK SUCH
INNOCENT LIVES.
>> AI'M /*.
>> I'M CONVINCED IN THE COMING
DAYS, EVEN TOMORROW THERE THERE
WERE WARNING SIGNS, MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES AND A FAMILY THAT
FELT THEY HAD NOWHERE TO TURN.
WE HAVE SEEN IT IN VIRGINIA TECH
AND THE SHOOTING OF GABRIELLE
GIFFORDS IN AURORA, COLORADO.
I'M SURE WE WILL SEE THAT.
WHAT WE WILL NOT SEE REALLY FOR
THE FAMILIES IS ANY KIND OF
EXPLANATION THAT WILL MAKE SENSE
OF THIS.
RIGHT NOW IT IS JUST SENSELESS.
>> JUST SO UNBEARABLY DIFFICULT
TO DIGEST, ESPECIALLY HERE ON
THE SCENE.
WITHOUT QUESTION SOMETHING HAD
TO BE TERRIBLY WRONG.
DREW GRIFFIN REPORTING FOR US
LIVE.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
THERE'S ONE NAME YOU WILL LIKELY
HEAR MORE OF.
HER NAME IS KATLIN ROY.
SHE IS A FIRST GRADE TEACHER AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
SHE IS BEING HAILED AS A HERO.
SHE SAVED A NUMBER OF STUDENTS
IN HER CLASSROOM.
SHE SPOKE EXCLUSIVELY WITH DIANE
SAWYER EARLIER.
HAVE A LISTEN.
>> IN MY MIND I'M THINKING, YOU
KNOW, AS A 6, 7-YEAR-OLD, WHAT
ARE YOUR THOUGHTS?
WHAT ARE YOUR -- I'M THINKING
THAT I HAVE TO ALMOST BE THEIR
PARENT.
LIKE I HAVE TO TELL THEM, YOU
KNOW SO I SAID TO THEM.
I NEED YOU TO KNOW THAT I LOVE
YOU ALL VERY MUCH AND THAT IT'S
GOING TO BE OKAY.
BECAUSE I THOUGHT THAT WAS THE
LAST THING THEY WERE GOING TO
HEAR.
I THOUGHT WE WERE ALL GOING TO
DIE.
I DON'T KNOW IF THAT IS OKAY.
YOU KNOW TEACHERS.
BUT I WANTED THEM TO KNOW
SOMEONE LOVES THEM AND LAST
THING THAT THEY HEARD NOT THE
GUN FIRE IN THE HALLWAY.
JUST HORRIBLE.
HORRIBLE.
>> INCREDIBLY EMOTIONAL STORY.
>> I'M JOINED BY THE HOPKINS
FAMILY, BOB AND HIS CHILDREN
JULIA AND BOBBY.
BOB, I WANT TO ASK YOU ABOUT A
FRIEND OF YOURS WHO'S A
BASKETBALL COACH HERE IN TOWN
WHO HAS TWO CHILDREN ATTENDING
SANDY HOOK.
ONE OF THOSE CHILDREN WAS A
FIRST GRADER WHO WITNESSED
SOMETHING ABSOLUTELY
UNBELIEVABLE.
I WANT YOU TO RECOUNT FOR ME THE
STORY IF YOU WILL.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
JUST SPOKE TO THEM AN HOUR OR SO
AGO.
ANY WAY, HIS YOUNG SON WAS IN
CLASS AND THE SHOOTER BROKE IN
TO THE CLASSROOM AN AND IN FRONT
OF HIS EYES GUNNED DOWN THE
TEACHER.
HE WAS ASTUTE ENOUGH TO TAKE A
COUPLE OF THE STUDENTS AND HE
RAN OUT THE DOOR BEHIND THE BACK
OF THE SHOOTER AND RAN OUT OF
THE SCHOOL AND CONTINUED TO RUN
FOR A HALF MILE UNTIL HE HIT THE
MAIN ROAD.
A STRANGER PICKED UP THE KIDS
AND TOOK THEM TO THE NEWTOWN
POLICE DEPARTMENT.
UNBE KNOWNst TO THE PARENTS WHEN
THEY WENT TO TALK TO THE STATE
TROOPERS, ET CETERA, THEIR SON
WAS UNACCOUNTED FOR.
SO THEY TOLD THEM TO LOOK IN THE
WOODS, GO DOOR TO DOOR, TALK TO
PEOPLE AND FOR AN HOUR OR SO
THEY HAD NO IDEA WHERE THEIR SON
WAS.
THEY CALLED THE POLICE
DEPARTMENT A COUPLE OF TIMES AND
THEY HAD NO RECORD OF HIM BEING
THERE.
FINALLY AFTER AN HOUR AND A HALF
THEY CALLED AND WERE RELIEVED TO
FIND OUT THEIR SON HAD BEEN
DROPPED OFF AT THE POLICE
DEPARTMENT SAFE LEN SOUND.
>> AT THAT TIME THEY MUST HAVE
THOUGHT THE WORST.
>> THEY THOUGHT THE WORST.
IT WAS VERY DIFFICULT TIME FOR
THEM.
HE SAID IT WAS THE WORST HOUR
AND A HALF HE'S EVER EXPERIENCED
IN HIS LIFE.
>> POLICE INTERVIEWED THIS FIRST
GRADER, I'M GUESSING HE'S 6, 7
YEARS OLD.
>> HE'S 6 YEARS OLD.
THEY DID INTERVIEW HIM SINCE HE
WAS THERE.
>> WHAT WAS HE ABLE TO TELL
THEM?
WHAT DETAILS.
>> THEY ASKED HIM, THE INTERVIEW
WAS VERY ELEMENTARY BUT THEY
ASKED WHAT HE SAW.
ASKED HIS RECOLLECTION OF THE
ROOM.
HE SAID I SAW A BUNCH OF SILVER
BULLETS ON THE FLOOR OF THE
CLASSROOM AND WHEN I GOT OUT TO
THE HALL I SAW A BUNCH OF
BULLETS IN THE HALL AND THEY
WEREN'T SILVER.
THEY WERE RED SO UNFORTUNATELY
COVERED IN PLOOD IN THE HALLWAY
AND FROM THAT POINT HE JUST RAN
AND SPRINTED AT THE SCHOOL.
>> DID HE GIVE A DESCRIPTION ANY
FURTHER ABOUT THE SHOOTER, HIS
FACE?
DID THE SHOOTER SAY ANYTHING.
DID HE HAVE A LOOK IN HIS EYE,
ANYTHING LIKE THAT?
>> HE DIDN'T SAY THE SHOOTER
SAID ANYTHING.
HE DESCRIBED WHAT HE LOOKED
LIKE.
IT IS A VERY ELEMENTARY
DESCRIPTION BECAUSE HE'S 6 YEARS
OLD.
HIS DESCRIPTIVE SKILLS ARE NOT
THAT ACUTE.
>> JULIA, YOU HAVE A DIFFERENT
STORY.
YOU ARE IN THE MIDDLE SCHOOL
HERE IN TOWN.
YOU WENT IN TO LOCKDOWN RIGHT
AWAY AS SOON AS THIS HAPPENED.
DID YOU KNOW WHAT WAS HAPPENING?
I KNOW EVERYONE HAS CELL PHONES
AND MIGHT HAVE BEEN TEXT
MESSAGES BUT DID YOU KNOW WHAT
WAS GOING ON?
>> NO.
I HAD NO CLUE MANY WHAT WAS
GOING ON UNTIL THE FIRST HOUR.
WE WERE IN LOCKDOWN.
A TEACHER SAID THERE WAS A
SHOOTING DOWN THE ROAD.
>> YOU HAVE A CLASSMATE WHO HAS
A LITTLE BROTHER AT THE SCHOOL.
>> THE BOY I WAS SITTING NEXT TO
DURING THE LOCKDOWN, HIS LITTLE
BROTHER ENDED UP DYING.
>> HOW DID HE FIND THAT OUT?
>> I'M NOT SURE.
I HAVEN'T TALKED TO HIM YET
TODAY BUT I KNOW DURING THE
LOCKDOWN HE DIDN'T SAY ANYTHING.
I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW HE HAD A
LITTLE BROTHER AT SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL UNTIL I FOUND OUT HIS
BROTHER HAD DIED.
>> HE HADN'T BEEN CONCERNED AT
THE TIME OF FINDING OUT THE FATE
OF HIS BROTHER WHILE HE WAS IN
LOCKDOWN IN YOUR CLASSROOM.
>> IT DIDN'T SEEM LIKE IT.
>> BOBBY, YOU WERE IN ANOTHER
SCHOOL, AS WELL.
AND YOU ALSO FWHENT TO LOCKDOWN.
WHAT WAS THE EXPERIENCE FOR YOU?
WHAT HAPPENED.
>> IT WAS A LITTLE DIFFERENT
BECAUSE WE WERE IN CHURCH AT THE
TIME, SCHOOL MASS AND MONDAY
SE --
MONSIGNOR SAID WE NEEDED TO END
MASS AND GO IN TO LOCKDOWN AND
WE SAT AND WAITED.
WE COULD HEAR SIRENS FOR AN
HOUR.
>> DID YOU, LIKE YOUR SISTER,
ALSO EVENTUALLY FIND OUT WHAT
WAS GOING ON?
>> YEAH.
WE EVENTUALLY WENT BACK TO THE
SCHOOL AND MY CLASS WAS LOCKED
DOWN IN THE BASEMENT.
OUR TEACHERS TOLD US THERE HAD
BEEN A SHOOTING AND THERE WERE
FATALITIES BUT I DIDN'T KNOW THE
SERIOUSNESS OF IT UNTIL MY DAD
PICKED ME UP FROM SCHOOL AND ON
THE CAR RIDE HE SAID THERE WERE
QUITE A FEW FATALITIES.
>> ARE YOU OKAY?
>> WE WENT TO THE VIGIL AT 7:00
WHICH WAS EMOTIONAL.
>> YOU ARE AWFULLY YOUNG TO BE
DIGESTING.
NONE OF US IS HANDLING THIS WELL
AND YOU ARE AWFULLY YOUNG, YOU
AND YOUR SISTER.
>> IT DIDN'T REALLY SINK IN.
I WAS NUMB UP UNTIL THE VIGIL
AND THEN I THINK EVERYONE BROKE
DOWN AT THE VIGIL BECAUSE IT WAS
SO SAD TO SEE EVERYONE THERE AND
SEE ACTUALLY 28 CANDLES ON THE
ALTER TO REPRESENT THE VICTIMS.
>> ACTUALLY JUST PASS THE MIC TO
YOUR DAD.
BOB, AN INCREDIBLE MOMENT AT THE
VIGIL.
THERE WAS A LETTER READ FROM THE
POPE.
>> IT WAS A LETTER WRITTEN BY
POPE BENEDICT TO OUR COMMUNITY
SPECIFICALLY, WHICH WAS VERY
TOUCHING.
AND VERY MEANINGFUL AND MEANT A
GREAT DEAL TO THE WHOLE
COMMUNITY.
ON TOP OF THAT IT WAS EMOTIONAL
FOR US IS MONTH SENIOR WEISS
TALKED ABOUT IN HIS HOMILY THE
TIME HE SPENT WITH THE 20
FAMILIES TODAY AND IN PARTICULAR
MENTIONED TWO LITTLE ANGELS, ONE
OF WHOM THE MOTHER OF THE VICTIM
SAID SHE WENT OUT RECENTLY AND
GOT HER FIRST COMMUNION DRESS
AND HER DAUGHTER WAS VERY
EXCITED ABOUT THAT AND THE OTHER
LITTLE ANGEL WAS GOING TO BE
PLAYING AN ANGEL IN OUR SCHOOL
PLAY AT SAINT ROSE NEXT WEEK.
IT WAS A POIGNANT STORY AND VERY
EMOTIONAL FOR US TO HEAR AND
DIGEST.
>> HOW IS YOUR FRIEND, THE
BASKETBALL COACH WHOSE CHILD
WENT THROUGH THIS HARROWING
ORDEAL?
>> I THINK THE BEST WAY TO
DESCRIBE IT IS TRAUMATIZED.
HE'S A WONDERFUL MAN, WONDERFUL
PERSON, WONDERFUL FAMILY.
ALTHOUGH HE IS INCREDIBLY
GRATEFUL THAT HIS SON IS SAFE,
HIS HEART IS CERTAINLY BLEEDING
FOR THE OTHER CHILDREN IN THE
CLASSROOM BECAUSE TWO OF HIS
SONS CLASSMATES DID PARISH IN
THE SAGA THEY TOLD YOU.
WHEN THE GUNMAN CAME IN, THAT
WAS THE SECOND CLASSROOM HE CAME
IN AND TWO OF THIS BOY'S
CLASSMATES WERE KILLED TODAY.
>> AND HE WITNESSED IT.
>> HE WITNESSED HIS OWN TEACHER
BEING SHOT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
OUR HEARTS GO OUT TO ALL OF YOU
HEAR.
THE NATION IS IN MOURNING WITH
EVERYBODY HERE IN NEWTOWN.
I HOPE YOU ARE GOING TO BE OKAY
AND HUG YOUR KIDS TIGHT.
>> WE WILL.
>> THANK YOU.
>> COMING UP NEXT, THE HASKINS
FAMILY JUST TOUCHED ON THE VIGIL
AND THE MESSAGE THAT CAME FROM
HALF WAY AROUND THE WORLD.
THE GOVERNOR WAS HERE, IN THE
SENATORS WERE HERE.
WE WILL GIVE YOU A BETTER FEEL
FOR WHAT IT WAS LIKE INSIDE THE
CHURCH LATER ON.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS STEVE.
HE LOVES RISK.
BUT WHETHER
HE'S CLIMBING EVEREST,
SCUBA DIVING THE
GREAT BARRIER REEF WITH SHARKS,
OR JUMPING INTO THE MARKET,
HE GOES WITH PEOPLE HE TRUSTS,
WHICH IS WHY HE TRADES
WITH A COMPANY
THAT DOESN'T NICKEL AND DIME
HIM WITH HIDDEN FEES.
SO HE CAN WORRY
ABOUT OTHER THINGS,
LIKE WHAT THE MARKET IS DOING
AND BEING READY,
NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENS,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE,
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
>> THIS IS A COMMUNITY OF 27,000
PEOPLE.
IT IS QUIET AND SPACIOUS AND THE
HOUSES WHERE TREES STRETCH FOR
LONG PERIODS BETWEEN HOUSES AND
STILL A CLOSE TOWN.
AND PEOPLE KNOW EACH OTHER.
AND THAT'S WHY THEY NEEDED
SOMETHING, ANYTHING TO TRY TO
COME TOGETHER AFTER THE HORRORS
THAT THEY WERE FORCED TO ENDURE
TODAY.
THE FACT THAT SO MANY OF THEIR
CHILDREN IN THIS COMMUNITY WILL
NO LONGER BE WITH THEM.
THEY GATHERED AT A CATHOLIC
CHURCH IN TOWN CALLED SAINT ROSE
OF LIMA.
JASON CARROLL WAS THERE FOR THE
VIGIL AND IT WAS STANDING ROOM
ONLY.
THERE ARE HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE
THAT CAME OUT.
AS YOU SAID, THEY WANTED
SOMETHING, ANYTHING.
THEY WERE LEANING ON EACH OTHER
AND LEANED ON THEIR FAITH AND
THAT'S WHY THEY CAME HERE TODAY.
NO QUESTION ABOUT IT.
SPOKE TO A DEACON WHO SAID, AS
YOU SAID, WHEN YOU HAVE A
COMMUNITY THIS CLOSE IT SHOULD
BE NO SURPRISE.
WHEN YOU HAVE HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE
THAT COME OUT, MOST OF THEM AT
THE CHURCH TONIGHT KNEW SOMEONE
AT THE SCHOOL.
IF IT WASN'T A CHILD IT WAS A
PARENT.
IF IT WASN'T A PARENT IT WAS A
TEACHER.
IF IT WASN'T A TEACHER IT WAS AN
ADMINISTRATOR.
THAT'S WHY THEY CAME HERE TODAY
FOR COMFORTING WORDS THAT THEY
GOT FROM MONSIGNOR ROBERT WEISS
WHO READ A LETTER FROM THE POPE.
>> I CONVEY MY HEART FELT GRIEF
AND THE ASSURANCE OF MY PERSONAL
PRAYERS TO THE VICTIMS AND THEIR
FAMILIES.
TO ALL OF THOSE IN THE COMMUNITY
OF NEWTOWN AND ESPECIALLY THE
PARISH OF SAINT ROSE OF LIMA.
IN THE AFTERMATH OF THE
SENSELESS TRAGEDY, I ASK GOD OUR
FATHER TO CONSOLE ALL OF THOSE
WHO MOURN AND SUSTAIN THE ENTIRE
COMMUNITY WITH THE SPIRITUAL
STRENGTH WHICH TRIUMPHS OVER
VIOLENCE BY THE POWER OF
FORGIVENESS, HOPE AND
RECONCILING LOVE.
>> AND ONE OF THE DEACONS HERE
AT THE CHURCH WHEN I SPOKE TO
HIM ABOUT WHAT HE WAS DOING HE
SAID THROUGHOUT THE DAY HE HAD
RECEIVED 100 PEOPLE THAT COME
THROUGH CHURCH DOORS LOOKING FOR
COMFORT AND ANSWERS.
MANY OF THEM ASKING WHY, WHY
SOMETHING LIKE THIS COULD HAPPEN
AND ALL HE COULD SAY IS I TOLD
THEM SOMETIMES THERE ARE NO
ANSWERS.
NOT NOW.
IT IS TOO SOON.
MAYBE THIS IS SOMETHING ONLY GOD
CAN ANSWER.
>> JASON, ONE OF THE ADULTS, ONE
OF THE SIX ADULTS KILLED IN THE
SCHOOL WAS THE SCHOOL PRINCIPAL
NAMED DAWN HOCHSPRUNG
.
HAVE YOU LEARNED ANYTHING ABOUT
HER?
>> YOU ARE HEARING SO MUCH ABOUT
HER FROM SO MANY PEOPLE OUT
HERE.
47 YEARS OLD, TWO DAUGHTERS
THREE STEP DAUGHTERS.
SHE HAD BEEN THE PRINCIPAL AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SINCE JUNE
OF 2010.
SHE WAS CONSTANTLY TWITTERING.
SO PROUD OF HER SCHOOL.
TWITTERING ABOUT THE FOURTH
GRADERS JUST THIS WEEK.
FROM ALL ACCOUNTS SHE WAS A
WOMAN WHO LOVED HER STUDENT AND
HER JOB.
WHEN WE TALK ABOUT THIS CLOSE
COMMUNITY IT NO SURPRISE TO FIND
A MAN OUT HERE WHO KNEW HER AND
KNEW HER WELL AND I WANT YOU TO
LISTEN TO WHAT HE HAD TO SAY
ABOUT HER.
>> DAWN THE PRINCIPAL AT SANDY
HOOK I HAD DINNER WITH HER LAST
SPRING.
SHE WAS AN INCREDIBLE EDUCATOR
AND TO LOSE SOMEBODY LIKE THAT
IN OUR DISTRICT IT IS SAD
BECAUSE THEY LOST A LEADER TODAY
AT SANDY HOOK.
MY PRAYERS WILL BE FOR, YOU
KNOW, OUR COMMUNITY, AS WELL.
>> AS YOU HEARD HIM SAY, LOST A
LEADER IN THIS COMMUNITY.
DEALING WITH THIS LOSS, DEALING
WITH THE PAIN AND SUFFERING,
THIS IS WHAT THIS COMMUNITY WILL
BE HAVING TO TRY TO COPE WITH
FROM THIS POINT ON I MEAN FOR
DAYS, WEEKS, MONTHS AND
CERTAINLY FOR THE PARENTS OF
THOSE CHILDREN.
THERE'S NO SAYING HOW LONG THEY
WILL BE DEALING WITH THEIR
GRIEF.
>> SO DISTRESSING, JASON, TO
KNOW THE PRINCIPAL HAD JUST THIS
FALL IMPLEMENTED A BRAND NEW
SECURITY SYSTEM WHERE YOU HAD TO
GET BUZZED IN AT 9:30 IN THE
MORNING AND YET THIS WAS
PERPETRATED AGAINST HER SCHOOL.
JASON CARROLL REPORTING FOR US
LIVE ACROSS TOWN FROM WHERE I
AM.
PART OF THE REASON I AM WHERE I
AM RIGHT NOW IS THAT THE MEDIA
HAS BEEN GETTING REGULAR UPDATES
AT THIS LOCATION, NOT ONLY FROM
THE STATE POLICE BUT ALSO FROM
CONNECTICUT'S GOVERNOR WHO HAS
COME AT REGULAR INTERVALS NOT
ONLY AT THE LOCATION TO BRIEF US
BUT HE HAS SPOKE ON THE THE
FAMILIES.
THE FAMILIES GIVEN THE TERRIBLE
NEWS THEY WOULD NOT BE REUNITING
WITH THEIR CHILDREN AND HE MADE
ANOTHER STOP AT THE VIGIL JASON
JUST REPORTED ON.
HERE'S SOME OF THE THINGS HE
TOLD THOSE IN GRIEF.
>> GOOD EVENING, EVERYONE.
MONTH SENIOR, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH FOR OPENING THIS VERY
BEAUTIFUL CHURCH SO THAT WE
MIGHT IN A COMMUNAL WAY FIND
SOLACE IN ONE ANOTHER.
AS A RESULT OF THE UNSPEAKABLE
HAVING OCCURRED IN THIS
COMMUNITY.
PEOPLE'S CHILDREN, BROTHER AND
SISTERS WERE TAKEN FROM THEM.
PEOPLE'S SPOUSES, TEACHERS AND
ADMINISTRATORS WERE TAKEN FROM
US.
YET WE STAND IN A CHURCH AND
MANY OF US TODAY IN THE COMING
DAYS WILL RELY UPON THAT WHICH
MAY HAVE BEEN TAUGHT AND THAT WE
INHERENTLY BELIEVE THAT THERE IS
FAITH FOR A REASON.
AND THAT FAITH ITSELF IS GOD'S
GIFT FOR ALL OF US.
IN THESE TIMES OF TROUBLES WHEN
THE UNTHINKABLE HAPPENS IN OUR
VERY MIDST, OUR FAITH IS TESTED.
NOT JUST IN THE RELIGIOUS SENSE.
NOT JUST NECESSARILY OUR FAITH
IN GOD, BUT OUR FAITH IN
COMMUNITY AND WHO WE ARE AND
WHAT WE COLLECTIVELY ARE.
IT'S IN SO MANY WAYS PERMISSIBLE
TO HAVE THOSE THOUGHTS AND THOSE
DOUBTS ABOUT WHO WE ARE AND WHAT
WE ARE AND WHAT COMMUNITY REPS.
BUT THEN WE TURN TO UNDERSTAND
AS WE TURN AROUND IN THIS ROOM
AND RECOGNIZE OUR FRIENDS AND
OUR NEIGHBORS, THOSE WE ARE DONE
THINGS FOR AND THOSE WHO HAVE
DONE THINGS FOR US.
THIS IS A GREAT AND BEAUTIFUL
COMMUNITY LOCATED IN A GREAT AND
BEAUTIFUL STATE AND A GREAT AND
BEAUTIFUL NATION.
IN THE COMING DAYS AND IN THE
COMING WEEKS, I WOULD PRAY WITH
YOU WILL ALL EMBRACE ONE
ANOTHER.
THAT YOU LIFT ONE ANOTHER UP.
THAT YOU UNDERSTAND THE
DIFFICULTIES THAT YOU
COLLECTIVELY WILL UNDERGO.
KEEP IN YOUR PRAYERS THE
CHILDREN WHO LOST THEIR LIVES
TODAY.
KEEP IN YOUR PRAYERS THE ADULTS
WHO LOST THEIR LIVES TODAY.
UNDERSTAND THAT A TEST IS JUST
THAT, THAT WHICH WE RISE TO AND
ANSWER AND RESPOND TO.
IN THE COMING DAYS, AS MANY OF
US PREPARE TO CELEBRATE THE
BIRTH OF CHRIST, UNDERSTAND THAT
THAT, TOO, WILL BRING SORROW AS
WE THINK OF THESE INSTANCES THAT
HAVE HAPPENED TO CLOSE TO THESE
DAYS.
THAT THAT TOO WILL PASS AND BE
OVERCOME.
IN ALL OF OUR PRAYERS AND THE
PRAYERS AND HOPES OF ALL OF THE
PUBLIC OFFICIALS ASSEMBLED HERE
TODAY AND IN THE PREFERENCE OF
YOUR -- I BRING THE CONDOLENCES
OF THE ENTIRETY OF THE STATE TO
YOU THE MEMBERS OF THIS
COMMUNITY.
MAY GOD BLESS YOU.
MAY GOD BLESS OUR CHILDREN WHO
ARE WITH US TODAY AND THOSE WHO
WERE TAKEN AWAY.
AND MAY GOD BLESS THE ADULTS WHO
LOST THEIR LIVES TODAY.
THANK YOU.
>> I WANTED TO SHARE WITH YOU
ONE OF THE MORE POIGNANT STORIES
THAT I LEARNED TODAY FROM A
NURSE NAMED MAUREEN.
SHE WANTED TO VOLUNTEER.
WHEN SHE HEARD WHAT WAS GOING ON
AT THE SCHOOL, SHE AND ANOTHER
NURSE RACED TO THE SCHOOL TO
HELP AND FOUND THEMSELVES
SURPRISED THERE WAS NOTHING FOR
THEM TO DO.
SADLY, THEY BEGAN TO UNDERSTAND
THAT THERE WOULD BE NO MORE
SURVIVORS COMING OUT OF THE
SCHOOL.
SO THEY MADE THEIR WAY TO THE
FIRE STATION WHICH WAS A STAGING
AREA FOR PARENTS TO BE REUNITED
WITH THEIR KIDS.
OF COURSE IT WAS A STAGING AREA
WHERE A LOT OF PARENTS WOULDN'T
BE REUNITED WITH THEIR CHILDREN
EITHER.
THE SAD STORY SHE TOLD ME IS THE
MOMENT THAT UNFORTUNATELY THE
AUTHORITIES HAD TO TELL THESE
PARENTS THERE WERE NO MORE
SURVIVORS.
ANOTHER WITNESS WHO WAS IN THAT
AREA SAID THAT THE CRIES AND THE
WAILS WERE OVERWHELMING.
IT WAS ONE OF THE MORE DIFFICULT
THINGS TO HAVE TO UNDERGO.
THERE WERE TWO PRIESTS ON THE
SCENE, AS WELL.
TWO GRIEF COUNSELORS THAT WERE
THERE TO TRY TO HANDLE WHAT WAS
GOING TO HAPPEN WITH THESE
APPROXIMATELY 50 PEOPLE.
IF YOU THINK OF IT, THERE WERE
20 KIDS AND THEY ALL HAVE
PARENTS.
ROUGHLY 50 PEOPLE HAD TO ENDURE
THAT TERRIBLE MOMENT WHEN THEY
WERE TOLD THEY WOULD LIKELY
NEVER SEE THEIR CHILDREN AGAIN.
COMING UP, A WOMAN WHO WORKS AT
A DAY CARE HERE IN TOWN TELLS US
THAT MANY OF HER DAY CARE
STUDENTS HAD GRADUATED TO BECOME
STUDENTS AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
SHEZ SHE'S GOING TO TALK TO US
IN A MOMENT.
Music is a universal language.
But when I was in an accident...
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
Information on my phone.
Connection to doctors who
get where I'm from.
And tools to estimate what
my care may cost.
So I never missed a beat.
We're more than 78,000
people looking out for
more than 70
million Americans.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.
>>> WOOR LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT TONIGHT IN A STORY
THAT OVERWHELMED MANY PEOPLE AS
IT BEGAN TO UNFOLD TODAY.
IT BEGAN AS A STORY WE HAVE
OFTEN COVERED BEFORE.
SHOTS MAY HAVE RUNG OUT AT A
SCHOOL, BUT AS THE DETAILS
ROLLED IN, AND AS THE MAGNITUDE
OF THIS HORROR UNFOLDED, IT WAS
ASTOUNDING THE SHEER NUMBERS
THAT WERE INVOLVED.
HERE'S HOW THE DAY PLAYED OUT.
>> WE ARE FOLLOWING THIS REPORT
THAT THERE'S BEEN A SHOOTING AT
AN ELEMENT INDUSTRY SCHOOL, AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL NAMED SANDY
HOOK.
>> THE INTERCOM CAME ON AND SHE
HEARD A SCREAM AND GUNSHOT, TWO
GUNSHOTS.
>> OFF-DUTY TROOPERS RESPONDED
TO THE SCHOOL AND WITH NEWTOWN
POLICE IMMEDIATELY UPON ARRIVAL
ENTERED THE SCHOOL AND BEGAN A
COMPLETE ACTIVE SHOOTER SEARCH
OF THE BUILDING.
>> THEY HAD TO HIDE IN THE
CLOSET AND THEY WERE QUIET.
THE CHILDREN WERE OBVIOUSLY VERY
SHAKEN.
THEY WERE CRYING IN THE CLOSET.
>> I SAW SOME OF THE BULLETS
GOING PAST THE HALL AND THEN A
TEACHER PULLED ME IN TO HER
CLASSROOM.
>> THE POLICE CAME IN AND IT'S
LIKE IS HE IN HERE AND HE RAN
OUT.
AND THEN OUR TEACHER, THEN
SOMEBODY YELLED GET TO A SAFE
PLACE.
>> I HEARD THE PRINCIPAL IS SHOT
AND KILLED.
I HEARD SOME KIDS WERE SHOT.
A TEACHER, MRS. HAMMONDS WAS
SHOT.
>> 18 CHILDREN WERE PRONOUNCED
DEAD AT THE SCHOOL.
TWO WERE TRANSPORTED TO AREA
HOSPITALS AND PRONOUNCED DEAD AT
THE HOSPITALS AND SIX ADULTS
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCHOOL.
>> THE PERPETRATOR OF THE CRIME
IS DEAD, AS IS AN INDIVIDUAL WHO
THE PERPETRATOR LIVED WITH.
>> ADAM LANZA'S OLDER BROTHER,
RYAN LANZA BEING TAKEN IN TO
CUSTODY TODAY IN HOBOKEN.
THE 24-YEAR-OLD RYAN LANZA IS
NOT CHARGED WITH ANYTHING.
AT THIS POINT HE IS BEING
QUESTIONED.
>> THERE'S A RELATED SCENE THAT
WE DISCOVERED AS WE WERE
CONTINUING THE CRIMINAL
INVESTIGATION.
>> I ASK GOD, OUR FATHER, TO
CONSOLE ALL OF THOSE WHO MOURN
AND SUSTAIN THE COMMUNITY WITH
THE SPIRITUAL STRENGTH THAT
TRIUMPHS OVER VIOLENCE BY THE
POWER OF FORGIVENESS, HOPE AND
RECONCILING LOVE.
>> THIS WAS THE SECOND DEADLIEST
SCHOOL SHOOTING IN AMERICAN
HISTORY.
20 YOUNG CHILDREN LOST THEIR
LIVES, AGES 5 TO 10.
WHILE THE REST OF THEIR
CLASSMATES WERE ROBBED OF THEIR
INNOCENCE AFTER WITNESSING THIS
TRAGEDY, THESE PARENTS WILL
FOREVER BE MOURNING.
I WANT TO INTRODUCE YOU TO
MICHELLE.
SHE USED TO WORK AT A DAY CARE
CENTER AND WATCH MARYLAND OF THE
CHILDREN IN THE SCHOOL AT THE
TIME OF THE SHOOTING.
HOW DID YOU FIND OUT WHAT WAS
HAPPENING TODAY?
>> EARLIER THIS AFTERNOON I
CONTACTED A FAMILY THAT I HAVE
KEPT IN TOUCH WITH FOR MANY
YEARS AND I ASKED IF THEY WERE
OKAY AND HE SAID THEY WERE HOME
SAFE AND SOUND BUT TO PRAY FOR
THOSE WHO WERE SO UNFORTUNATE.
>> DO YOU KNOW IF ANY OF THE
KIDS THAT ATTENDED YOUR DAY CARE
WERE VICTIMS IN THIS RAMPAGE.
>> ALL OF THEM AT THIS POINT ARE
HOME SAFE AND SOUND.
>> IT YOU MUST HAVE BEEN AN
ENORMOUS RELIEF.
>> IT IS, YES.
>> HAVE YOU HAD A CHANCE TO TALK
TO THEIR PARENTS OR FIND OUT HOW
THEY ARE DOING?
>> I DID.
THEY ARE VERY FORTUNATE THEY ARE
HOME AND, YOU KNOW, TO PRAY FOR
THE ONES THAT WERE NOT SO
FORTUNATE IN THE SHOOTING
EARLIER TODAY.
THEY ARE VERY, HAPPY THAT THEIR
LITTLE ONES ARE HOME.
>> YOU WORK AT THIS DAY CARE,
CALLED THE LITTLE EXPLORERS DAY
CARE.
>> YES.
>> ARE YOU CLOSED?
ARE YOU GOING TO BE ABLE TO WORK
ON MONDAY?
IS ANYTHING CHANGING IN TERMS OF
YOUR SECURITY MEASURES.
HOW WILL THIS GO FORWARD LOOKING
AFTER LITTLE ONES?
>> I WORKED THERE SEVERAL YEARS
AGO.
BUT IT IS UP AND RUNNING AS OF
TODAY IT.
>> IS RUNNING.
>> IT IS.
>> YOU ALSO HAVE A FRIEND WHO IS
A TEACHER AT THE SCHOOL.
>> YES.
I FOUND OUT SHE WAS INJURED
EARLIER TODAY AND LAST TIME I
SPOKE TO THE FAMILY THAT KEEPS
IN TOUCH WITH HER SHE WAS STILL
THE HOSPITAL.
>> HOW WAS SHE INJURED?
>> SHE WAS SHOT IN THE FOOT.
>> DO YOU KNOW IF SHE WAS IN
THAT MEETING WHEREBY THE
PRINCIPAL AND THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST WERE SHOT DEAD?
THERE WAS A REPORT THAT THREE OF
THESE TEACHERS IN THE MEETING
HAD EMERGED TO THE HALLWAY WHEN
THE GUNSHOTS RANG OUT AND ONLY
ONE CAME BACK AND WAS INJURED IN
THE FOOT OR LEG AND I'M TRYING
TO PUT TOGETHER WHETHER IT MIGHT
HAVE BEEN YOUR FRIEND.
>> IT MIGHT HAVE BEEN THE SAME
PERSON BUT I'M UNCERTAIN OF
THAT.
BUT I KNOW SHE WAS SHOT IN THE
FOOT.
>> HOW ARE YOU PROCESSING THIS?
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
>> IT IS HARD TO HANDLE SEEING I
HAD ALL ALL OF THESE KID SINCE
THEY WERE 3.
I KEEP IN TOUCH WITH ALL OF THE
FAMILY AND THANKFUL THEY ARE
HOME ON THIS HOLIDAY WITH
PARENTS AND PRAYING IF THE ONES
THAT WERE INJURED.
>> NEWTOWN IS SUCH A BEAUTIFUL
AND QUIET COMMUNITY.
EVERYONE WHO GOES THROUGH A
TRAGEDY SAYS IT WOULD NEVER
OCCUR IT WOULD HAPPEN THERE AND
IT WASN'T OCCUR IT THAT WOULD
HAPPEN HERE.
>> KIT HAPPEN ANYWHERE.
IT IS SMALL, QUAINT AND QUIET
BUT IT IS UNFORTUNATE THAT IT
DID HAPPEN.
>> YOU AND YOUR NEIGHBORS GOING
TO BE OKAY?
>> YES, I'M HOME WITH MY
PARENTS.
WE'RE GOING TO BE OKAY.
>> MICHELLE, THANK YOU FOR
JOINING US.
>> THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>>> I WANT TO GO BACK TO MY
COLLEAGUE DREW GRIFFIN.
THERE WERE A NUMBER OF WEAPONS
RECOVERED AT THE SCHOOL.
ALL OF THEM, A THREE WERE
OWNED BY THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER.
THEY WERE REGISTERED.
CONNECTICUT HAS SOME OF THE
TOUGHEST GUN LAWS ON THE BOOKS
IN THIS NATION AND THERE ARE NOW
CALLS FOR EVEN STRICTER GUN
CONTROL.
DREW GRIFFIN HAS BEEN LOOKING IN
TO THAT PART OF THE STORY, AS
WELL.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL ME?
>> WE KNOW THE GUNS WERE LEGALLY
OWNED BECAUSE OF CONNECTICUT'S
VERY STRICT GUN LAWS.
LET ME TELL YOU WHAT THEY ARE.
THE TWO HANDGUNS IN THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT WOULD REQUIRE A
CERTIFICATE OF POSSESSION.
A FIVE-YEAR LICENSE, AS IT IS,
TO OBTAIN AND OWN THAT WEAPON.
IT ALSO COMES WITH THE
REQUIREMENT THAT YOU GO THROUGH
A TRAINING COURSE, A HANDGUN
SAFETY COURSE.
AS FOR THAT ASSAULT RIFLE, IF
THAT IS INDEED AN OPERATING SEMI
ASSAULT RIFLE, THAT GUN IS
BANNED IN CONNECTICUT.
HOWEVER, IF THE GUN WAS
PURCHASED AND IN THE POSSESSION
OF THE MOTHER PRIOR TO OCTOBER
OF 1993, THAT GUN WOULD HAVE
BEEN GRANDFATHERED IN TO HER
POSSESSION.
ALTHOUGH THAT WOULD HAVE TO BE
REGISTERED TO HER WITH THE
STATE, AS WELL.
THERE ARE VERY STRICT GUN LAWS
IN THE STATE OF CONNECTICUT, AND
YES, THESE GUNS WERE ALL LEGALLY
OWNED.
>> DREW, THE SHOOTER IN THIS
CASE, ADAM LANZA, HE HAD NO
CRIMINAL RECORD.
NO ONE CAN FIND ANYTHING THAT
HE'S DONE WRONG.
WOULD THAT HAVE FACTORED IN TO
WHETHER HE WOULD HAVE HAD
GREATER ACCESS TO GUNS IN THE
STATE?
>> BEING 20 YEARS OLD, THERE'S
NO WAY LEGALLY HE COULD HAVE
PURCHASED A HANDGUN, CERTIFICATE
OR NOT.
HE WAS TOO YOUNG.
HE COULD NOT HAVE PURCHASED THAT
ASSAULT RIFLE BECAUSE IT IS
BANNED.
YOU CAN'T BUY THEM OR OBTAIN
THEM OR POSSESS THEM IN THE
STATE OF CONNECTICUT UNLESS YOU
HAVE THAT GRANDFATHER CLAUSE FOR
A GUN IN THE PAST.
SO LEGALLY SPEAKING, HE COULD
NOT HAVE OWNED THESE GUNS.
I THINK WE WILL TURN TO THE FACT
THAT THEY WERE IN THE MOTHER'S
HOME.
OBVIOUSLY ACCESSIBLE, AND HOW
WERE THEY STORED?
DID THE MOM KNOW HE WAS USING,
TRAINING WITH THE GUNS?
WE WILL LOOK AT THOSE TYPE OF
ISSUES, BUT AS FOR THE
CONNECTICUT GUN LAWS, TO SAY
THIS KID COULD HAVE GONE OUT AND
BOUGHT THESE GUNS, THE ANSWER IS
LEGALLY NO.
>> AGAIN, A GLOCK, A SIG SAUER
WERE FOUND ON HIS PERSON IN THE
SCHOOL AFTER HE APPARENTLY
KILLED HIMSELF AND A
BUSHMASTER.223 WAS FOUND THE
VEHICLE HE HAD LEFT ERRATICALLY
PARKED OUTSIDE IN FRONT OF THE
SCHOOL.
THANK YOU FOR LOOKING IN TO
THAT.
DREW GRIFFIN REPORTING LIVE FOR
US.
I WANT TO TALK YOU THROUGH HOW
THIS PLAYED OUT.
THIS PARTICULAR SCHOOL -- WHILE
NOT A LARGE SCHOOL IT IS
SOMEWHAT SPREAD OUT.
SANDY HOOK AS A SQUARE FORMATION
AND THE SHOOTER DEFINITELY TOOK
A CERTAIN PATH THROUGH THE
SCHOOL.
BUT AS THEY SAID, THE OFFICIALS
WHO SPOKE WITH US, HE WAS NOT
RUNNING THROUGH THE HALLS AND
SHOOTING.
HE WAS VERY SPECIFIC WHERE HE
TARGETED.
HAVE A LOOK AT HOW TOM FOREMAN
LAYS THIS OUT FOR US.
>> 9:30 THIS MORNING, IT WAS A
FORMAL START TO THE DAY OUT
HERE.
600 STUDENTS IN THE CLASS HERE.
50 FACULTY MEMBERS.
WE DON'T HAVE A COMPLETE READ ON
THE LAYOUT OF THE SCHOOL OR THE
TIME LINE.
WE ARE TRY PIECE TOGETHER ALL
DAY LONG AS INVESTIGATORS HAVE
AND WE HAVE SOME IDEA.
THE DAY WAS GETTING UNDERWAY.
HAD BEEN UNDERWAY 30 MINUTES.
THERE WAS A MEETING UP HERE
INVOLVING THE PRINCIPAL, SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST AND OTHER ADULTS IN
THE AREA.
AND THEN 9:40, AS BEST WE CAN
TELL FROM WITNESSES, TEN MIGHT
BE MINUTES LATER HE ENTERS THE
BUILDING.
WE'RE NOT SURE HOW HE GOT PAST
THE SECURITY SYSTEM OR IF IT WAS
LOCKED A THAT POINT.
WE KNOW POLICE HAVE LOOKED HARD
AT A CAR IN THE FIRE LANE.
IT IS SURROUND BY TAPE THE BEST
I CAN TELL THEM SUGGESTION IS
THAT IN FACT THE GUNMAN DID COME
THROUGH THE FRONT DOOR HERE IN
TO THE SCHOOL.
ALMOST IMMEDIATELY PEOPLE
THROUGHOUT THIS BUILDING
REPORTED HEARING GUN FIRE.
9:41 IS WHEN THE CALLS STARTED
TO COME IN TO 911.
THE PRINCIPAL, THE VICE
PRINCIPAL AND SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST IN THIS MEETING
ACCORDING TO WITNESSES WENT OUT
TO THE HALL AND WENT TOWARD THAT
GUN FIRE TO SEE WHAT WAS
HAPPENING.
THERE WAS SHOUTING.
MANY SHOUTS AND SHOTS AND THE
VICE PRINCIPAL CAME BACK IN THE
MEETING ROOM WOUNDED BUT THE
OTHER TWO DID NOT.
AUTHORITIES SAY ALL OF THE
SHOOTING HAPPENED REALLY IN A
RELATIVELY SHORT PERIOD OF TIME
AND THEY SAID THE GUNMAN DID NOT
ROAM AROUND BUT GENERALLY STAYED
IN TWO ROOMS AND A HALLWAY UP
HERE.
THAT'S WHERE THEY ULTIMATELY
FOUND HIM.
9:45, TEACHERS WERE TRYING TO
PROTECT STUDENTS ALL THROUGHOUT
THE SCHOOL.
SOME NEAR THE GYM SAID THEY WERE
TOLD TOLL HIDE IN CLOSETS AND
SOME OTHERS SAY THEY WERE LET
OUTSIDE TO FLEE.
IT'S NOT CLEAR IF THAT HAPPENED
WITH THE TEACHERS OR LATER WITH
THEM BEING HELPED OUT BY SOME
LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS.
NONETHELESS, WE KNOW THERE WAS A
REAL EFFORT THROUGHOUT THE
SCHOOL TO GET ALL OF THESE KIDS
IN TO SOME SORT OF SAFETY.
THIS PICTURE, BY THE WAY, FROM
THE NEWTOWN BEE AND THERE WERE
TEACHERS TRYING TO DO SOMETHING
ABOUT IT AND THEY DIDN'T KNOW
WHAT WAS GOING ON.
IT IS NOT CLEAR AT WHAT POINT IN
THIS PROCESS THAT THE GUNMAN
DIED.
LAW OFFICIALS SAY NO OFFICERS
FIRED A WEAPON, BUT THEY DID
FIND HIM DEAD IN ONE OF THE
ROOMS THERE, THE SUGGESTION
PROBABLY THAT HE KILLED HIMSELF.
WE WILL GET MORE DETAILS AS WE
GO ON.
THIS IS WHAT WE KNOW.
WHEN LAW ENFORCEMENT AGENTS
ARRIVED AT THE SCHOOL, THEY
IMMEDIATELY SET UP A PERIMETER
AROUND IT.
IT WAS STATE AND LOCAL POLICE
AND OFFICERS SPRED SPREAD
THROUGHOUT THE BUILDING.
THEY ENTERED TO SECURE ROOMS, TO
FIND STUDENT AND MAKE SURE IF A
GUNMAN WAS ACTIVE IN THERE THAT
THEY GOT HIM UNDER CONTROL AND
KILLED HIM IF THEY HAD TO.
THEN THEY QUICKLY STARTED TO
LEAD STUDENTS AWAY FROM THE
SCHOOL TRYING TO GET THEM OUT TO
SAFETY.
THIS WAS A HORRENDOUS EVENT AS
YOU KNOW.
VERY DIFFICULT EVEN FOR THE
OFFICERS INVOLVED BECAUSE THEY
HAD TO, AS YOU SAID, TELL MANY
OF THESE CHILDREN, AVERT YOUR
EYES, CLOSE YOUR CRIES BECAUSE
THEY KNEW THEY WERE GOING TO
LEAD THEM PAST MANY OF THE
VICTIMS.
OH, TOM, SUCH A DIFFICULT DETAIL
TO LISTEN TO THAT THE CHILDREN
HAD TO AVERT THEIR EYES AS THEY
ESCAPED THE SCHOOL.
IT IS NOT OFTEN THAT THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
SHEDS A TEAR IN PUBLIC.
TODAY IT HAPPENED.
YOU'LL SEE THE PRESIDENT'S
MOVING TRIBUTE TO THE VICTIMS
AFTER THE BREAK.
>>> THIS EVENING MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT
IN AMERICA WILL DO WHICH IS HUG
OUR CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER.
AND WE'LL TELL THEM THAT WE LOVE
THEM.
AND WE'LL REMIND EACH OTHER HOW
DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT.
THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT NOW.
IN HARD DAYS TO COME, THE
COMMUNITY NEEDS US TO BE AT OUR
BEST AS AMERICANS, AND I WILL DO
EVERYTHING IN MY POWER, AS
PRESIDENT, TO HELP.
OUR PHARMACIST
RECOMMENDED IT.
AND THAT MAKES ME FEEL
PRETTY GOOD ABOUT IT.
AND THEN I HEARD ABOUT A STUDY
LOOKING AT MULTIVITAMINS
AND THE LONG TERM
HEALTH BENEFITS.
AND WHAT DO YOU KNOW?
THEY USED CENTRUM SILVER
IN THE STUDY.
MAKES ME FEEL EVEN BETTER,
THAT'S WHAT I TAKE.
SORRY, WE TAKE.
[ Male Announcer ] CENTRUM.
THE MOST RECOMMENDED.
MOST PREFERRED. MOST STUDIED.
CENTRUM,
ALWAYS YOUR MOST COMPLETE.
THERE'S A HEALTH COMPANY THAT
CAN HELP YOU STAY THAT WAY.
WHAT'S HEALTHIER THAN THAT?
FOR MUCH OF THE DAY THERE WAS SO
MUCH CONFUSION ON WHO THE
SHOOTER WHO PERPETRATED THIS
TERRIBLE ACT WAS.
THERE WAS CONFUSION BECAUSE HE
WAS USING I.D. THAT BELONGED TO
HIS BROTHER A BROTHER IN
HOBOKEN, CONNECTICUT AND THAT
CONFUSION LED POLICE TO THAT
BROTHER'S FRONT DOOR.
HE'S BEEN ARRESTED NOW, AS WELL
AND JOHN BERMAN HAS THE DETAILS
OF HOW THIS PLAYED OUT.
>> THIS STREET WHERE I AM
STANDING NOW HAS BEEN THE SITE
OF A HUGE AMOUNT OF ACTIVITY
TODAY AND A HIGH NUMBER OF
QUESTIONS.
BEHIND ME IS THE APARTMENT
BUILDING WHERE LIVES THE BROTHER
OF THE SHOOTING SUSPECT,
24-YEAR-OLD RYAN LANZA.
HE WAS LED TO A CAR IN HANDCUFFS
BY LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS
EARLIER TODAY.
TAKEN IN TO CUSTODY FOR
QUESTIONING.
ALSO, QUESTIONED ACCORDING TO TO
SOURCES TELLING CNN TWO
ROOMMATES OF THE BROTHER WHO
LIVES HERE.
THEY ARE BELIEVED TO HAVE NO
CONNECTION AT ALL TO THE
SUSPECT.
THIS BUILDING BEHIND ME IS A
FIVE-STORY BUILDING WITH TWO AND
THREE-BEDROOM APARTMENTS.
ON THIS STREET EARLIER TODAY
WERE HOBOKEN CITY POLICE, JERSEY
CITY POLICE.
THERE WERE BOMB SQUAD
REPRESENTATIVES, ALTHOUGH THEY
DID NOT GO IN TO THE APARTMENT
BUILDING.
ALSO THE FBI HAD A PRESENCE
HERE.
THE FBI DID REMOVE MATERIALS
FROM THIS APARTMENT INCLUDING,
WE BELIEVE, SOME KIND OF
COMPUTER.
THERE ARE QUESTIONS ABOUT WHY
THE BROTHER WAS TAKEN IN TO
CUSTODY AT ALL, ESPECIALLY IN
HANDCUFFS.
ONE POLICE OFFICER ON THE SCENE
DID TELL ME THAT THERE
APPARENTLY WAS SOME CONFUSION
THAT THE BROTHER'S I.D. MAY HAVE
BEEN FOUND ON THE SHOOTER'S BODY
IN CONNECTICUT.
THAT IS ONE POLICE OFFICER WHO
TOLD ME THAT.
WE ARE NOT SURE AT THIS TIME IF
RYAN LANZA IS STILL IN CUSTODY.
AGAIN, HE'S THE BROTHER OF THE
APPARENT SHOOTING SUSPECT WHO
WAS DEAD AND ALSO THE SON OF A
WOMAN WHO WAS KILLED TODAY.
>> ALL RIGHT.
JOHN BERMAN REPORTING FROM
HOBOKEN.
TO ADD TO THAT, THE LANZA'S
FATHER WAS QUESTIONED BY POLICE.
THEY ARE NOT SUSPECTS BUT HAVE
BEEN QUESTIONED FOR ANY KIND OF
INFORMATION THEY CAN LEND TO
THIS.
I MENTIONED BEFORE IT IS NOT
OFTEN YOU SEE A PRESIDENT IN
TEARS BUT IT WASN'T BUT A FEW
HOURS THIS NEWS HIT THE
PRESIDENT'S DESK PRETTY QUICKLY
AND THE TOOK THOUGH AIRWAYS TO
OFFER HIS COMFORT AND SUPPORT TO
THE VICTIMS HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> THIS AFTERNOON I SPOKE WITH
GOVERNOR MALLOY AND FBI DIRECTOR
MUELLER.
I OFFERED GOVERNOR MALLOY MY
CONDOLENCES ON BEHALF OF THE
NATION.
AND MADE IT CLEAR HE WILL HAVE
EVERY SINGLE RESOURCE THAT HE
NEEDS TO INVESTIGATE THIS
HEINOUS CRIME CARE FOR THE
VICTIMS, COUNSEL THEIR FAMILY.
WE'VE ENDURED TOO MANY OF THESE
TRAGEDIES IN THE LAST FEW YEARS
AND EACH TIME I LEARN THE NEWS I
REACT NOT AS A PRESIDENT BUT AS
ANYONE ELSE WOULD AS A PARENT.
THAT IS ESPECIALLY TRUE TODAY.
I KNOW THERE'S NOT A PARENT IN
AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME WEATHER WELLING GRIEF THAT
I DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF FIVE TO 10 YEARS
OLD.
>> THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS.
MEN AND WOMEN WHO DEVOTED THEIR
LIVES TO HELPING OUR CHILDREN
FOLLOW THEIR DREAMS.
SO OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN TODAY.
FOR THE PARENTS AND
GRANDPARENTS, SISTERS AND
BROTHERS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN, AND FOR THE FAMILIES
OF THE ADULTS WHO WERE LOST.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN FOR THE
PARENTS OF THE SURVIVORS, AS
WELL.
FOR AS BLESSED AS THEY ARE TO
HAVE THEIR CHILDREN HOME
TONIGHT, THEY KNOW THEIR
CHILDREN'S INNOCENCE HAS BEEN
TORN AWAY FROM THEM TOO EARLY
AND THERE ARE NO WORDS THAT WILL
EASE THEIR PAIN.
AS A COUNTRY, WE HAVE BEEN
THROUGH THIS TOO MANY TIMES.
WHETHER IT IS AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN NEWTON OR A SHOPPING
MALL IN OREGON, OR A TEMPLE IN
WISCONSIN, OR A MOVIE THEATER IN
AURORA, OR A STREET CORNER IN
CHICAGO.
THESE NEIGHBORHOODS ARE OUR
NEIGHBORHOODS.
THESE CHILDREN ARE OUR CHILDREN.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO COME
TOGETHER AND TAKE MEANINGFUL
REACTION TO PREVENT MORE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS, REGARDLESS
OF THE POLITICS.
THIS EVENING, MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT
IN AMERICA WILL DO, WHICH IS HUG
OUR CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER
AND TELL THEM THAT WE LOVE THEM
AND WE WILL REMIND EACH OTHER
HOW DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT.
AND THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT
NOW.
IN HARD DAYS TO COME, THAT
COMMUNITY NEEDS US TO BE AT OUR
BEST AS AMERICANS, AND I WILL DO
EVERYTHING IN MY POWER, AS
PRESIDENT, TO HELP.
BECAUSE WHILE NOTHING CAN FILL
THE SPACE OF A LOST CHILD OR
LOVED ONE, ALL OF US CAN EXTEND
THE HAND TO THOSE IN NEED TO
REMIND THAT THAT WE ARE THERE
FOR THEM, THAT WE ARE PRAYING
FOR THEM, THAT THE LOVE THEY
FELT FOR THOSE THEY LOST ENDURES
NOT JUST IN THEIR MEMORIES, BUT
ALSO IN OURS.
MAY GOD BLESDS THE MEMORY OF THE
VICTIMS AND IN THE WORDS OF SKIP
CHUR, HEAL THE BROKEN HEARTED
AND BIND UP THEIR WOUNDS.
>> WE ARE INDEED A NATION IN
MOURNING TONIGHT AND IT'S KNOWN
ACROSS THE WORLD WHAT HAPPENED
IN AMERICA IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THERE'S BEEN REACTION FROM WORLD
LEADERS WHO HAVE WRITTEN, WHO
HAVE MADE STATEMENTS ABOUT THIS
TRAGEDY, AND THEN THERE'S THE
REACTION FROM PEOPLE.
PEOPLE FROM ALL CORNERS OF THE
WORLD WHO NOW HAVE SOCIAL MEDIA
TO LET US KNOW TO LET THEIR
FRIENDS KNOW, TO LET EVERYONE
KNOW HOW THEY FEEL ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED.
JOSH HAS THE REACTION ON
TWITTER.
>> PEOPLE ALL OVER THE WORLD ARE
EXPRESSING THEIR SORROW AND
THEIR HORROR AT WHAT HAS
HAPPENED.
THIS IS NOW PART OF THE STORY.
THE GLOBAL REACTION.
IN THIS ERA WHERE YOU SEE THAT
IS ON SOCIAL MEDIA ESPECIALLY.
LOOK AT SOME OF THE TWEETS THAT
ARE GETTING A LOT OF ATTENTION.
ONE HERE IS FROM MIKE BLOOMBERG
IN NEW YORK.
HE SAID MY DEEPEST SYMPATHIES
ARE WITH FAMILIES AFFECTED AND
MY DETERMINATION TO STOP THIS
MADNESS IS STRONGER THAN EVER.
LET'S JUMP ACROSS THE FOND DAVID
CAMERON, PRIME MINISTER OF
BRITAIN.
MY THOUGHTS ARE WITH THOSE WHO
HAVE BEEN DEVASTATED BY THE
CONNECTICUT SHOOTINGS.
THE DEATH OF SO MANY CHILDREN IS
TRULY HEART BREAKING.
THIS IS GETTING A LOT OF
ATTENTION AND IT IS INTERESTING.
D
DEE PACK SHOP RA SAYS HE IS
OBSERVING SILENCE ON FACEBOOK
AND TWITTER IN REMEMBRANCE OF
THOSE WHO KILLED.
WE WILL SEE IF THAT CATCHES ON.
WE ARE TALKING TO YOU ACROSS
TWITTER AND ACROSS ALL
PLATFORMS.
THE REAL TRAGEDY IS WE LET IT
HAPPEN OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
ONE MORE SENT TO ME HERE.
HOLD YOUR CHILDREN TIGHT AND
THANK THE LORD FOR THEM.
ABSOLUTELY.
I'M DOING THAT AND I KNOW MANY
OF YOU ARE, AS WELL.
THE FACEBOOK PAGE FOR THE SCHOOL
IS GETTING A GOOD AMOUNT OF
ATTENTION, AS WELL.
PEOPLE ARE POSTING MESSAGES
THERE.
AND WE HAVE AN IREPORT FOR YOU
TO EXPRESS YOUR THOUGHTS AND
CONDOLENCES FOR THE COMMUNITY
AND THE VICTIMS AND IF AND
FAMILIES.
>> AS WE LEAVE YOU TONIGHT
THERE'S A VERY LARGE PROJECT
THAT LIES AHEAD FOR THE
INVESTIGATORS FOR THE POLICE,
FOR THE RESPONDERS HERE.
THIS WAS SUCH A MASSIVE CRIME
SCENE THAT THE PROCESSING OF IT
ALONE WILL TAKE AT LEAST
THROUGHOUT THE NIGHT WCH