>> I'M TELLING YOU, NEVER WORK
WITH ANIMALS OR FISH.
IT IS ALL FUN AND GAMES UNTIL
YOU HAVE TO PRY A LARGE-MOUTHED
BASS OFF GARY TUCHMAN'S NECK.
THIS ANCHOR WAS A PRO.
NO HARM DONE.
I JUST WANT TO POINT OUT THAT
CNBC STILL HAS A LONG WAY TO GO
IF IT REALLY WANTS TO MAKE
HISTORY IN THE FINANCIAL NEWS
BLOOPER DEPARTMENT.
>> AT NO POINT WERE YOU RUNNING
A GYM?
>> NO, NO.
RUNNING A GYM?
TO WORK OUT OR SOMETHING?
JESUS [ BLEEP ] CHRIST.
I COME ON THE NEWS FOR TWO
SECONDS AND YOU WANT TO -- EVERY
TIME I DO AN INTERVIEW, I GUY
WANTS TO OPEN HIS [ BLEEP ]
MOUTH.
CAN'T YOU [ BLEEP ] A ROUTINE
HERE.
>>> TODAY'S A SOLDIER WAS KILLED
IN KANDAHAR AFTER I VISITED THE
BASE.
IT IS A SAD REMINDER OF HOW
UNSAFE THIS COUNTRY REMAINS
AFTER 11 YEARS OF WAR.
I WILL ASK THE SECRETARY WHAT
HAPPENED NEXT AS AMERICAN TROOPS
PREPARE IT LEAVE AFGHANISTAN AND
ABOUT THE FIGHT FOR AL QAEDA,
LET'S GOOUTFRONT.
GOOD EVENING, I'M ERIN BURNETT
LIVE IN AFGHANISTAN FOR A
SPECIAL EDITION OF OF
"OUTFRONT."
I WANT TO WELCOME OUR VIEWERS
FROM AROUND THE WORLD.
THANKS FOR JOINING US.
A SOBERING REMINDER OF HOW
AMERICA'S WAR IS STILL NOT WON.
WE STILL DO NOT HAVE A SECURE
AFGHANISTAN.
TODAY, JUST HOURS AFTER I
WRAPPED UP AN INTERVIEW WITH THE
SECRETARY OF DEFENSE LEON
PANETTA IN KANDAHAR AT AN
AMERICAN BASE, THERE WAS A A
BRAZEN ATTACK JUST OUTSIDE THE
BIAS.
THE SUICIDE BOMBER STRUCK, THE
TALIBAN TOOK RESPONSIBILITY.
AN AMERICAN SOLDIER HAS WITHIN
KILLED.
TWO AFGHAN SOLDIERS WERE KILLED.
AMERICANS AND AFGHANS WERE
WOUNDED IN THIS ATTACK TODAY.
A TALIBAN SPOKESMAN NOT ONLY
CLAIMED RESPONSIBILITY FOR THE
ATTACK BUT PRAISED THE QUOTE
UNQUOTE BRAVE TALIBAN FIGHTER
WHO CARRIED IT OUT.
ALSO, HERE IN KABUL, SECRETARY
PANETTA MET WITH KARZAI AND
INVITED HIM IT MEET WITH
PRESIDENT OBAMA NEXT MONTH.
THE KEY QUESTION FOR THE LEADERS
IS WHERE DO THINGS NOW STAND AND
WHAT'S NEXT?
11 YEARS, TWO MONTHS AND SIX
DAYS.
>> WE WILL NOT TIRE, WE WILL NOT
FAULTER, AND WE WILL NOT FAIL.
>> PEACE AND FREEDOM WILL
PREVAIL.
>> JUST ONE MONTH AFTER 9/11 WBT
WAR AGAINST THE TALIBAN AND AL
QAEDA AND AFGHANISTAN, IT HAS
BEEN STEEP, MORE THAN 2,000
AMERICANS DEAD AND MORE THAN
18,000 WOUNDED.
642 BILLION U.S. DOLLARS SPENT.
AND AN UNTOLD NUMBER OF AFGHAN
CIVILIANS KILLED.
AT LEAST 12,000 IN THE LAST FIVE
YEARS.
WITH THAT SACRIFICE, CAME SOME
PROGRESS.
THE TALIBAN WAS REMOVED FROM
POWER AND --
>> I CAN REPORT TO THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE AND TO THE WORLD, THAT
UNITED STATES HAS CONDUCTED AN
OPERATION THAT KILLED OSAMA BIN
LADEN, THE LATER OF AL QAEDA.
>> AS COMBAT TROOPS PREPARE IT
COME HOME IN 2014, THE TALIBAN
IS RESURGING.
JUST THIS WEEK, A MEMBER OF THE
NAVY'S ELITE S.E.A.L. TEAM 6,
THE SAME GROUP WHO DIED TRYING
TO SAVE A DOCTOR ABDUCTED BY THE
TALIBAN.
AFGHAN TROOPS AREN'T READY TO
FIGHT THEM.
DEVERSION RATES ARE HIGH AND THE
UNITE HE NATION REPORTS
POLICEMEN ARE JOINING THE
TALIBAN.
EXTREMIST IN THE AFGHAN SECURITY
FORCES HAVE KILLED 33 AMERICANS
THIS YEAR.
AND AFGHAN CIVILIANS FEAR THE
FUTURE.
>> Translator: I DON'T A HUNDRED
PERCENT BELIEVE THERE ARE
NATIONAL ARMIES CAPABLE.
EVERYDAY WE HEAR OUR SOLDIERS
ARE KILLED IN THE INSECURE
PROVINCES.
>> 11 YEARS, 6 MONTHS AND 2
DAYS.
WHEN WILL THIS MISSION BE
ACCOMPLISHED?
THE ISSUE OF READINESS ON THE
PART OF AFGHAN SECURITY FORCES
TO TAKE OVER THE FIGHT AGAINST
AL QAEDA AND TERRORIST IN THIS
COUNTRY IS THE CENTRAL ISSUE TO
DETERMINE IF AMERICA STAYS AND
HOW MANY AMERICAN TROOPS WILL
CONTINUE TO SERVE IN THIS
COUNTRY.
THERE WAS A NEW PENTAGON REPORT
OUT THIS WEEK, IMPORTANT IT CAME
FROM THE PENTAGON.
THEY ARE TRYING TO TELL A STORY
OF IMPROVEMENT HERE, BUT
PENTAGON REPORT ITSELF SAID THAT
ONLY ONE UNDER 23 AFGHAN BRIGADE
SAYS ACTUALLY READY TO TAKE OVER
SECURITY IN THIS COUNTRY AND IN
AN ARMY WHERE 85% OF RECRUITS
ARE ILL LITERAL.
THE CHALLENGES CAN BE
OVERWHELMING.
I SPOKE SPECIFICALLY NO LEON
PANETTA TODAY IN KANDAHAR AND
ASKED HIM ABOUT THIS DAUNTING
CHALLENGE.
>> OBVIOUSLY THERE IS A, YOU
KNOW, A LITERACY PROBLEM WITH
REGARDS TO FORCES AND YOU KNOW,
WE CONTINUE IT TRY TO PREPARE
THEM FOR THE ABILITY TO TAKE
OVER ALL OF THIS SECURITY
RESPONSIBILITIES.
I GUESS, YOU KNOW, THE GOOD NEWS
IS THAT AS A RESULT OF THE
TRAINING EFFORT, THEY ARE
DEALING WITH ILLITERACY AND
PROVIDING QUICK CLASSES FOR
THESE INDIVIDUALS THAT GO INTO
THE ARMY, SO THEY ARE MEETING
THAT RESPONSIBILITY.
THEY ARE DEVELOPING THE KIND OF
TRAINING AND CAPABILITY THAT
THEY NEED.
BUT THIS IS AN AREA WE'RE JUST
GOING TO HAVE TO FOCUS ON
INTENSELY.
BECAUSE OVER THE NEXT TWO YEARS,
AND PARTICULARLY IN 2013, WE
HAVE TO REACH A STAGE WHERE A
HUNDRED PERCENT OF THE
OPERATIONS ARE IN THE HANDS OF
THE AFGHAN ARMY.
THAT'S GOING TO TAKE A LOT MORE
WORK.
>> SO IS THAT WHY THERE'S BEEN A
BIT OF A DELAY?
I WAS LOOKING AT HEADLINES A FEW
WEEKS AGO AND SAID WE WOULD HAVE
A TROOP COUNT DECISION IN A FEW
WEEKS.
THE HEADLINES A COUPLE DAYS AGO
WERE THAT WE WOULD HAVE A TROUPE
DECISION IN A FEW WEEKS.
WHAT IS CAUSING THAT DELAY?
ARE YOU NOT SURE OF THAT NUMBER?
WHERE IS THE DELAY?
>> NO, I THINK, YOU KNOW, I
THINK FIRST AND FOREMOST, THAT
GENERAL ALAN HAVING DEVELOPED A
CAMPAIGN PLAN FOR AFGHANISTAN IS
THE ONE THAT HAS TO COME FORWARD
WITH THE RECOMMENDATIONS AS TO
WHAT ENDURING PRESENCE WILL LOOK
LIKE AN HE IS PREPARED SEVERAL
OPTIONS.
WE HAVE REVIEWED THEM.
AND THEN ULTIMATELY THEY HAVE TO
BE PRESENTED TO THE NATIONAL
SECURITY COUNCIL WHICH REVIEWS
THEM AND THEN PRESENT IT TO THE
PRESIDENT FOR FINAL DECISION.
THAT TAKES TIME AND WE WANT TO
MAKE SURE, OBVIOUSLY, THAT WE
MAKE THE RIGHT DECISION WITH THE
SLICE OF THAT ENDURING PRESENCE.
>> THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO WORRY
THAT U.S. WILL HAVE TOO FEW
PEOPLE TO PROVIDE SECURITY
THAT'S REQUIRED.
SOMEONE SAID THAT NUMBER IS
20,000.
ANYTHING FEWER THAN THAT IS NOT
ENOUGH.
IS THAT FAIR?
>> YOU KNOW, IT DEPENDS ON THE
MISSIONS THAT WE'VE GOT TO BE
ABLE TO WORK ON IN THAT ENDURING
PRESENCE.
AND THE KEY MISSIONS ARE THE
FOLLOWING.
ONE IS COUNTERTERRORISM WHICH
MEANS IT CONTINUE TO CONFRONT AL
QAEDA.
AND THOSE THAT YOU KNOW, HAVE
ALWAYS CONTINUED TO PLAN ATTACKS
ON THE UNITED STATES.
WE JUST WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT
THERE IS NO AL QAEDA THREAT HERE
IN AFGHANISTAN.
SECONDLY, TO DOT TRAINING AND
ASSISTANCE THAT IS NECESSARY FOR
THE AFGHAN ARMY AND THIRDLY, TO
PROVIDE SOME OF THE ENABLING
CAPABILITY FOR THE FORCES THAT
ARE HERE.
THAT WILL DETERMINE THE NATURE
OF THE PRESENCE.
BUT THE BOTTOM LINE IS THAT, IF
WE'RE GOING TO ACCOMPLISH THE
MISSION, THE MAIN RESPONSIBILITY
HAS TO REST WITH THE AFGHAN
ARMY.
>> SO YOU'RE NOT YET SURE ON THE
NUMBER?
IT IS NOT LIKE YOU'RE JUST
WAITING FOR AN OUTSET, YOU'RE
NOT SURE ON THE NUMBER.
>> WE ARE WORKING INTENTLY RIGHT
NOW TO TRY TO DETERMINE WHAT
THAT WILL BE.
>> IT IS INTERESTING WHEN YOU
SAY A LOT HAS TO DO WITH THE
MISSION.
I WILL QUOTE THE PRESIDENT WITH
BE TO DEFEAT, DISRUPT AND
DESTROY AL QAEDA.
>> RIGHT.
>> IS THAT MISSION ACCOMPLISHED?
>> THE MISSION OF DEFEATING AND
DETERRING AL QAEDA, I THINK, IS
WELL ON THE WAY TOWARDS, YOU
KNOW, ACHIEVING THE MISSION WITH
REGARDS TO AFGHANISTAN.
AND THE THREAT THAT WE FACE
HERE.
WE CONTINUE TO FACE AL QAEDA
OBVIOUSLY ELSEWHERE.
NOT ONLY IN PAKISTAN, BUT YEMEN
AND SOMALIA AND ELSEWHERE.
BUT WE HAVE HAD REMARKABLE
SUCCESS GOING AFTER SPECIAL
OPERATIONS AGAINST AL QAEDA HERE
AND WE'RE CONTINUING TO DO THAT.
I THINK THAT, YOU KNOW, THE MAIN
CHALLENGE HERE IS OBVIOUSLY TO
MAKE SURE THERE'S NO SAFE HAVEN
FOR AL QAEDA IN WHICH TO CONDUCT
ATTACKS BUT THE KEY IT THAT IS
AN AFGHANISTAN THAT CAN SECURE
AND GOVERN ITSELF.
THOSE TWO ARE INNER LOCKED IN
TERMS OF MISSION THATTED WITH IN
AFGHANISTAN.
>> WHAT IF THEY CHOOSE A
TALIBAN.
YOU KNOW, I'M VERY CONFIDENT
THAT THE AFGHAN PEOPLE WANT TO
BE SOVEREIGN.
THEY WANT TO BE INDEPENDENT.
THEY WANT TO BE FREE FROM THE
TALIBAN.
BUT THEY WANT TO BE ABLE TO
DETERMINE THEIR FUTURE.
AND THAT'S OKAY.
THAT'S WHAT NEEDS TO BE DONE
HERE.
JUST TO HAVE AN AFGHANISTAN THAT
CAN DETERMINE.
>> WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT DEFEATING
AL QAEDA, JUST THINKING ABOUT
SOME OF THE STATISTIC HERE,
THERE IS STILL INSURGENCY, 93
POLICEMEN IN ONE DAY JOINED THE
TALIBAN.
DO YOU THINK AL QAEDA WILL BE
DEFEATED, EVEN HERE?
>> I THINK YOU CAN REACH A POINT
WHERE YOU SO SIGNIFICANTLY
WEAKEN AL QAEDA THAT, YOU KNOW,
ALTHOUGH THERE MAY STILL BE A
FEW PEOPLE AROUND, THEY WON'T BE
ABLE TO CONDUCT THE OPERATIONS
THAT THEY'VE CONDUCTED IN THE
PAST AND THEY CERTAINLY WON'T BE
ABLE TO PLAN THE KIND OF ATTACKS
THAT AMERICA HAD HAPPEN TO IT ON
9/11.
AND THAT'S OUR GOAL, IS TO MAKE
SURE THAT DOESN'T HAPPEN AGAIN.
>> WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT AL QAEDA
AND WHERE IT IS, NOW WIDELY SEEN
AS A SAFE HAVEN FOR AL QAEDA AND
LINKED TO, INSPIRED BY, WHATEVER
THE WORDS MIGHT BE, DOES THE
UNITED STATES HAVE TO INTERVENE
IN MALLY?
>> WE'VE GOT TO GO AFTER AL
QAEDA WHEREVER THE HELL THEY'RE
AT AND MAKE SURE THEY HAVE NO
PLACE IT HIDE.
LET'S NOT FORGET, THE MAIN GOAL
OF AL QAEDA IS TO ATTACK THE
UNITED STATES.
AND WE AREN'T GOING TO ALLOW
THAT TO HAPPEN AGAIN.
IF WE AREN'T GOING TO ALLOW IT
TO HAPPEN, WE'VE GOT TO GO AFTER
THEM IN SOMALIA AND YES IN
YEMEN.
>> AS YOU ASSESS THREATS TO THE
HOMELAND, HOW BIG OF A THREAT IS
AL QAEDA?
>> I THINK WE HAVE SIGNIFICANTLY
WEAKENED THEIR ABILITY TO DO THE
KIND OF COMMAND AND CONTROL.
AND PLANNING THAT WOULD BE
NECESSARY TO CONDUCT ANOTHER
9/11 ATTACK.
AT THE SAME TIME, THEY STILL
CONTINUE TO THREATEN OUR
COUNTRY.
AND THEY STILL REPRESENT, I
THINK, PROBABLY THE MOST
IMPORTANT THREAT WE STILL FACE
IN THE WORLD.
>> ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH, SECRETARY.
>>> OUTFRONT, NEXT, VIOLENCE IN
AFGHANISTAN.
AN AMERICAN SOLDIER LOST HIS
LIFE IN A SUICIDE ATTACK BY THE
TALIBAN.
IT HAPPENED IN A BASE IN
KANDAHAR JUST A COUPLE HOURS
AFTER WE DID THAT INTERVIEW IN
KANDAHAR WITH THE DEFENSE
SECRETARY.
A SAD REMINDER OF HOW UNSAFE
THIS COUNTRY IS AFTER 11 YEARS
OF WAR.
WE WILL BE BACK IN JUST A
MOMENT, TALKING AND GETTING THE
OTHER SIDE OF THE STORY.
WHAT DO AFGHANS REALLY THINK
ABOUT THE SAFETY HERE?
THAT'S COMING UP, AFTER THIS.
YEAR-END EVENT.
SO, THE 5.3-LITER V8 SILVERADO
CAN TOW UP TO 9,600 POUNDS?
315 HORSEPOWER.
WHAT'S THAT IN
REINDEER-POWER?
[ laughs ]
[ pencil scratches ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHEVY'S GIVING MORE.
GET THE BEST OFFER
OF THE YEAR --
0% APR FINANCING FOR 60 MONTHS
PLUS $1,000 HOLIDAY BONUS CASH.
PLUS TRADE UP FOR AN ADDITIONAL
$1,000 TRADE-IN ALLOWANCE.
HURRY.
BONUS CASH ENDS JANUARY 2ND.
SHE ALSO LIKES
TO RIDE HER BIKE.
SHE KNOWS THE POTENTIAL
FOR MAKING OR LOSING MONEY
CAN POP UP ANYTIME.
THAT'S WHY SHE TRADES WITH
THE LEADER IN MOBILE TRADING.
SO SHE'S ALWAYS READY
TO TAKE ACTION,
NO MATTER HOW WILY...
OR WEIRD...
OR WONDERFULLY
THE MARKET'S BEHAVING...
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
SOMETHING THIS DELICIOUS
COULD ONLY COME FROM NATURE.
NEW NECTRESSE.
THE 100% NATURAL
NO-CALORIE SWEETENER
MADE FROM THE GOODNESS
OF FRUIT.
NEW NECTRESSE.
SWEETNESS NATURALLY.
TRY RUNNING FOUR.NING
A RESTAURANT IS HARD,
FORTUNATELY WE'VE GOT INK.
IT GIVES US 5X THE REWARDS
ON OUR INTERNET, PHONE
CHARGES AND CABLE,
PLUS AT OFFICE SUPPLY STORES.
REWARDS WE PUT RIGHT
BACK INTO OUR BUSINESS.
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
WE'VE EVER WANTED TO DO
AND INK HELPS US DO IT.
MAKE YOUR MARK
WITH INK FROM CHASE.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
>>> DESPITE THE ATTACK ON THE
KANDAHAR BASE A COUPLE HOURS
AFTER WE WERE THERE WITH THE
DEFENSE SECRETARY, THE MESSAGE
FROM THE UNITED STATES IS CLEAR.
TERRORISTS WILL NOT WIN HERE IN
AFGHANISTAN.
WHAT IS THE REALITY ON THE
GROUND?
OUT FRONT TONIGHT TWO MEN WHO
MAKE IT THEIR BUSINESS TO KNOW.
MATTHEW ROSE ENBURG WITH THE NEW
YORK TIMES BASED IN AFGHANISTAN
FOR THE LAST FOUR YEARS.
AND A FORMER MEMBER OF THE
AFGHAN PARLIAMENT.
I WANT IT BRING BOTH OF YOU GUYS
IN HERE.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR WAKING UP
IN KABUL.
I WANT IT ASK YOU ABOUT THIS
ATTACK.
IT HAPPENED A COUPLE HOURS AFTER
THE DEFENSE SECRETARY WAS IN
KANDAHAR.
THEY DON'T KNOW WHETHER IT WAS
RELATED TO HIS VISIT OR NOT.
GENERAL USE END EXAMPLE OF WHERE
INSURGENCE FAILED IN THE PAST.
THEY FAILED IN KANDAHAR AT THE
AIR BASE.
HE SAID THAT TWO HOURS BEFORE
THIS HAPPENED.
WHAT'S THE REALITY?
>> THEY FAILED.
THERE ARE THOUSANDS AND
THOUSANDS OF SOLDIERS THERE.
BUT THAT ROAD HAS BEEN BOMBED
BEFORE.
THE ENVIRONMENT, AROUND THE
CITY, IT IS SO UNSAFE WE HAVE A
REPORTER IN AFGHAN THAT WORKS
FOR US IN KANDAHAR CITY.
WON'T DRIVE WHERE THE SURGE IS
PLAYED OUT.
IF IT IS NOT SAFE ENOUGH FOR
HIM, NEVER MIND WESTERNERS.
WE CAN NEVER GO TO THOSE PLACES.
IT IS BETTER THAN IT WAS AT THE
HEIGHT OF THE SURGE.
IT WAS MORE VIOLENT THAN IT WAS
UNDER 2008, 2009.
>> WHAT IS YOUR ANSWER IT THAT,
WHEN SOMEONE SPENDS A LOT OF
TIME HERE, WHAT DID WE
ACCOMPLISH.
>> THERE ARE AREAS MUCH SAFER,
BUT NOT SAFE ENOUGH YET.
THAT'S THE THING.
WE ARE LEAVING NOW AND IS THIS
DONE?
IS IT READY TO HAND OVER TO THE
AFGHANS?
THE GENERAL SAYS, THE QUESTION
IS SUSTAINABILITY.
CAN WE SUSTAIN IT.
WE WILL FIND OUT NEXT SUMMER AND
I DON'T THINK -- IT IS AN OPEN
QUESTION.
>> AND YOU JUST HEARD THE
SECRETARY OF DEFENSE SAY WE'VE
HAD SUCCESS IN DISRUPTING AL
QAEDA.
HE IS SAYING, WE'RE ON THE PATH.
HE IS CAREFUL TO SAY THAT.
THAT THE REALITY WHEN THE U.S.
LEAVES, HOW BIG IS THE RISK THAT
THIS PLACE AGAIN BECOMES A
SANCTUARY FOR TERRORISM OR
WHATEVER WORD YOU WANT TO PUT ON
IT?
>> I DON'T BLAME AMERICAN
OFFICIALS TO PAINT A ROSEY
PICTURES.
IT IS NOT AS ROSEY AS THEY THINK
OR AS PESSIMIST AS SOME THING.
I THINK THE SOLUTION IS IN THE
ASPECTS OF WHAT WILL HAPPEN
AFTER THE U.S. LEAVES, WHICH IS
AFGHAN GOVERNMENT'S
RESPONSIBILITY AND ALSO THE
TURNING POINT WILL BE THE AFGHAN
PRESIDENTIAL ELECTIONS.
I THINK THE AFGHAN PEOPLE CAN
AND WILL HELP THE SECURITY
SITUATION IF THEY ARE CONFIDENT
ENOUGH THAT THEY HAVE THE
GOVERNMENT TO RELATE TO, THAT
THEY CAN BE CONFIDENT, AND RULE
OF LAW, THE GOVERNANCE THAT HAS
TO BE PROVIDED.
ALL THOSE THINGS ARE A BIG
QUESTION.
IF WE DON'T HAVE THAT ELECTION
THE WAY IT SHOULD BE, BUT THEN
SECURITY WILL BE DETERIORATING
BECAUSE PUBLIC SUPPORT WILL NOT
BE THERE FOR THE GOVERNMENT TO
HELP RECEIVE SUPPORT FROM THE
AFGHAN PEOPLE.
>> AND IT IS INTERESTING.
A LOT OF PEOPLE WE SPOKE TO,
MATT, SAYS WE TAKE IT FOR
GRANTED THAT THERE IS EITHER A
CIVIL WAR OR REAL RISK OF CIVIL
WAR WHEN THE U.S. LEAVES.
WE WENT TO A BIZARRE.
JUST ASKED AFGHANS WHAT THEY
THOUGHT AND WHETHER THEY THINK
IT IS GOOD THAT THE UNITED
STATES IS LEAVING.
SHEER WHAT THEY SAID.
>>.
>> Translator: AMERICA SHOULD
LEAVE AFGHANISTAN IMMEDIATELY.
GO BACK TO AMERICA.
THE MUSLIMS THEMSELVES SHOULD
LEAD AFTER AFGHANISTAN AND BUILD
IT WITH THEIR HANDS.
>> AFTER THEY LEAVE THE AFGHAN
GOVERNMENT CAN LEAD THE PEACE TO
THE COUNTRY.
WE DON'T NEED THE AMERICANS.
>> IS THERE NO NEED FOR AMERICA
TO STAY?
I KNOW THERE'S NATIONALISM,
THERE'S PRIDE.
BUT WHAT'S THE TRUTH?
>> WE DO NEED TO STAY IF -- TO
HOLD THIS TOGETHER.
NOW DOES OUR PRESENCE HERE HELP?
THAT'S A MUCH BIGGER QUESTION.
THERE'S A STRONG CASE TO BE MADE
THAT WE PROVIDE AN ACCELERANT.
WE PROVIDE A REASON FOR PEOPLE
TO FIGHT AGAINST US.
I THINK THAT'S WHAT THESE GUYS
ARE SAYING.
THEY SAY LOOK, WE HAVE TO STEP
UP ON OUR OWN.
I THINK THAT'S WHAT THEY WANT.
THEN THERE IS READINESS.
POST 24 TEAM BETWEEN THE
CIVILIAN AND MILITARY AID IS
LIKE $8 BILLION A YEAR.
AFGHANISTAN'S TOTAL REVENUE IS A
BILLION.
HOW MUCH LONGER CAN WE PAY AND
IS THERE AN EXPECTATION THAT
THEY CAN AT SOME POINT PAY FOR
IT THEMSELVES?
THAT'S NOT REALLY CLEAR.
>> HERE IN AFGHANISTAN, IN KABUL
THAT WE'RE UNDER, WEALTHY PEOPLE
LIVE HERE, DRUG LORDS, WARLORDS,
MINISTERS, ALL KINDS OF PEOPLE.
THE ROADS ARE TERRIBLE.
THEY SAY THEY ARE TERRIBLE
BECAUSE THEY WANT THEM TERRIBLE
BECAUSE THEY DON'T WANT SUICIDE
BOMBERS TO COME.
WILL THAT CHANGE?
>> THAT'S A POOR EXCUSE, I
THINK, FOR NOT PAYING ATTENTION
TO YOUR JOB AND RUN A COUNTRY.
BUT I THINK THING WILL CHANGE IN
THIS COUNTRY GRADUALLY IN SOME
CASES.
THAT THE BIGGEST PROBLEMS OF
AFGHAN GOVERNMENT AND AFGHAN
PEOPLE HAVE IS, THINGS
DETERIORATED FROM THE TOP DOWN.
AND WE HAVE TO FIX IT THAT WAY
FROM THE TOP DOWN.
>> MAFIA FAIR WORD TO USE FOR
GOVERNMENT?
>> MAFIA IS A VERY
UNDERSTATEMENT.
BECAUSE THIS GOVERNMENT AND THE
ECONOMY AND THE EVEN -- EVE EVEN
THE SMALLEST THINGS CAN RUN IN
CIRCLE HE OF GROOVES.
PEOPLE WHO ARE MONOPOLIZING
THINGS.
FROM THE PRESIDENCY, ALL THE WAY
DOWN TO THE LOWEST THING THAT
PRODUCES SOME MAJOR INCOME FOR
PEOPLE.
THE WEALTH WAS NOT SPREAD,
MANAGEMENT OF THE COUNTRY AND
THE BIG CITIES IS REALLY
TERRIBLE.
AND PEOPLE FEEL THAT.
THAT'S WHY PEOPLE ARE NOT
HELPING THE TALIBAN.
THEY'RE STANDING ON THE
SIDELINES.
AND WE HAVE TO CHANGE THAT.
>> MATT, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>>> ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A BREAK, BUT
WHEN WE COME BACK, WE'RE GOING
TO BE TALKING WITH THE FUTURE OF
AFGHANISTAN WITH THE DEPUTY
FOREIGN MINISTER.
WE'LL BE BACK IN  AT.
♪
AIDS IS GOING TO LOSE.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
>>> WELCOME BACK TO A SPECIAL
EDITION OF "OUTFRONT."
WE ARE LIVE FROM KABUL,
AFGHANISTAN, TONIGHT.
AND THE ATTACK OUTSIDE A U.S.
MILITARY BASE IN KANDAHAR TODAY
WAS ONLY THE LATEST BLOW IN A
NATIONAL SECURITY SITUATION,
WHICH IS INCREDIBLY PRECARIOUS
IN THIS COUNTRY.
345-2550
investors want.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Like no ATM fees, worldwide.
And no nuisance fees.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Plus deposit checks with
Mobile Deposit.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
And manage your cash
and investments
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
with Schwab's mobile app.
No wonder Schwab Bank has grown
to over 70 billion in assets.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
So if you're looking for a bank
that's in your corner,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
not just on the corner...
Call, click or visit to start
banking with Schwab Bank today.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Aunt Sally's
singing again.
It's a tradition,
honey.
[ singing
Christmas carols ]
mmmm.
[ Female Announcer ]
Make new traditions
with Pillsbury Grands!
Cinnamon Rolls.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO A SPECIAL
EDITION OF "OUTFRONT."
WE ARE LIVE FROM KABUL,
AFGHANISTAN, TONIGHT.
AND THE ATTACK OUTSIDE A U.S.
MILITARY BASE IN KANDAHAR TODAY
WAS ONLY THE LATEST BLOW IN A
NATIONAL SECURITY SITUATION,
WHICH IS INCREDIBLY PRECARIOUS
IN THIS COUNTRY.
I SPOKE EARLIER WITH THE DEPUTY
FOREIGN MINISTER HERE IN
AFGHANISTAN AND I ASKED HIM IF
THIS ACT OF TERROR TODAY CAUGHT
HIM BY SURPRISE.
>> NO.
I'M NOT SURPRISED.
TERRORISM REMAINS A THREAT FOR
AFGHANISTAN.
THAT'S THE NUMBER ONE THREAT TO
AFGHANISTAN'S SECURITY AND ALSO
BY EXTENSION, TO THE SECURITY OF
THE REGION AND THE REST OF THE
WORLD.
AFGHANISTAN, UNFORTUNATELY,
CONTINUES TO BE ONE OF THE WORST
VICTIMS OF TERRORISM.
>> CAN YOU WORK WITH THE
TALIBAN?
I MEAN, I'M CURIOUS, YOU'VE MADE
ALL THIS PROGRESS IN CERTAIN
AREAS.
YOU'VE TRIED TO DO THINGS FOR
WOMEN'S RIGHTS AND YOU'VE TRIED
TO HAVE A MORE FREE AND OPEN
SOCIETY.
WILL THE TALIBAN BE A PART OF
THAT?
WILL THEY ACTUALLY BE A PLAYER?
>> WELL, THEY HAVE TO BE.
THAT'S ONE OF OUR RED LINES THAT
WE'RE ABSOLUTELY READY AND I
THINK THIS IS, IN THE INTEREST
OF PEACE IN AFGHANISTAN, AND
ABSOLUTELY DESIRABLE.
NONETHELESS, THERE HAVE TO BE
SOME RED LINES.
SOME OF THE ACHIEVEMENTS THAT
WE'VE HAD IN THE LAST TEN YEARS
CAN'T BE NEGOTIATED.
WE HAVE A CONSTITUTION THAT
GIVES RIGHTS TO MEN AND WOMEN IN
AFGHANISTAN.
WE HAVE ESTABLISHED A DEMOCRATIC
PERSON THAT'S VERY YOUNG, STILL,
A LONG WAY TO GO, BUT IT'S STILL
ONE OF OUR BIGGEST ACHIEVEMENTS.
>> AND I THINK ABOUT THE BOMB
THAT HAPPENED TODAY IN KANDAHAR.
I WAS THINKING ABOUT SOME
ARTICLE THAT I READ IN THE GULF,
I TRAVELED THERE THIS WEEK.
A PRUDENTIAL POLICE CHIEF WAS
KILLED AND THERE WAS ANOTHER
ATTACK, OBVIOUSLY, LAST WEEK.
THE TALIBAN IS PURPOSELY, AND
THEY SAY, SPECIFICALLY TARGETING
GOVERNMENT OFFICIALS.
DO YOU FEEL THAT RISK EVERY DAY?
>> AS AN AFGHAN, YES.
AFGHANISTAN IS ON THE THREAT.
AFGHANISTAN FACES TERRORISM, AS
A THREAT, ON A DAY-TO-DAY BASIS.
SO I THINK THERE IS NO
DIFFERENCE BETWEEN MYSELF AND
THE AFGHANS WHO GOT,
UNFORTUNATELY, GOT KILLED AND
INJURED IN KANDAHAR TODAY.
>> AHEAD, YOU'LL MEET SERGEANT
FIRST CLASS JOSH BURNT.
HIS STORY IS AMAZING.
HE IS STATIONED AT THE STATION
WHERE A SUICIDE BOMBER KILLED
AFTER ARE AN AMERICAN
SERVICEMEMBER AND THREE OTHERS.
HE WILL TALK ABOUT WHY HE FEELS
IT IS IMPORTANT TO BE HERE.
WE'LL PLAY HIM A SPECIAL MESSAGE
THIS HOLIDAY SEASON FROM HIS
WIFE AND TWO CHILDREN.
AMERICANS BELIEVE THEY SHOULD BE
IN CHARGE OF THEIR OWN FUTURE.
HOW THEY'LL LIVE TOMORROW.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO A SPECIAL
EDITION OF "OUTFRONT."
WE ARE LIVE IN KABUL,
AFGHANISTAN, TONIGHT.
I WANT TO WELCOME OUR VIEWERS IN
THE UNITED STATES AND AROUND THE
WORLD.
WE'LL HAVE MORE ON OUR REPORTING
FROM AFGHANISTAN IN JUST A
MOMENT, BUT FIRST, WE WANT TO
UPDATE YOU ON SOME OF THE BIG
STORIES MAKING NEWS IN THE
UNITED STATES TONIGHT.
>>> SUSAN RICE, THE UNITED
STATES AMBASSADOR TO THE UNITED
NATIONS WILL NOT BE THE NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE.
A SOMEWHAT SURPRISING MOVE IN A
LETTER TO THE PRESIDENT,
PRESIDENT OBAMA, SHE WITHDREW
HER NAME FROM CONSIDERATION
TODAY.
SHE SAYS SHE'S CONCERNED THAT
HER CRITICISM OF HER HANDLING OF
THE ATTACK IN BENGHAZI WOULD
LEAD TO A LENGTHY AND DISRUPTIVE
AND COSTLY CONFIRMATION PROCESS.
THE PRESIDENT WILL MEET WITH
RICE TOMORROW AT THE WHITE
HOUSE.
>>> AND SPEAKING OF WHITE HOUSE
MEETINGS, PRESIDENT OBAMA AND
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER MET
AT THE WHITE HOUSE FOR ABOUT AN
HOUR TONIGHT.
AN IMPORTANT MEETING AND WE'RE
GLAD IT WAS AN HOUR.
MAYBE THEY CAN GET SOMETHING
DONE ON THE FISCAL CLIFF.
THE HOPE IS THAT THEY'LL HAVE A
MEETING OF THE MINDS ON THE TAX
HIKES AND THE AUTOMATIC SPENDING
CUTS THAT ARE SET TO STRIKE THE
UNITED STATES IN THE BEGINNING
OF JANUARY.
TIME IS RUNNING OUT.
THE FISCAL CLIFF IS 19 DAYS
AWAY.
AND OUR JESSICA YELLIN REPORTS
THAT SOME IN WASHINGTON BELIEVE
THAT A DEAL HAS TO BE DONE BY
TOMORROW IN ORDER TO GET IT
THROUGH CONGRESS BEFORE THE END
OF THE YEAR.
>>> AND BACK HERE IN KABUL,
AFGHANISTAN, WHERE WE ARE TAKING
A LOOK AT AMERICA'S 11-YEAR WAR,
THE LONGEST WAR HERE IN AMERICA,
WHERE DO THINGS STAND TODAY?
WHAT IS THE FUTURE FOR
AFGHANISTAN?
ONE OF THE MAIN CONCERNS HERE ON
THE GROUND IS SECURITY.
JUST A FEW HOURS, WE HAD A STARK
REMINDER OF THAT HERE, WHEN
THERE WAS A SUICIDE ATTACK RIGHT
AT THE ENTRANCE OF THE KANDAHAR
AIRFIELD.
THAT WAS A BASE THAT THE DEFENSE
SECRETARY, LEON PANETTA HAD
INTERVIEWED TWO YEARS BEFORE.
THE EXPLOSION KILLED ONE SERVICE
MEMBER AND TWO AFGHAN CIVILIANS.
THE TALIBAN CLAIMED
RESPONSIBILITY, CALLING THE
BOMBER A QUOTE/UNQUOTE BRAVE
FIGHTER.
PANETTA LATER SAID TERRORISTS
RESORT TO THESE TYPES OF ATTACKS
IN ORDER TO CREATE CHAOS.
WELL, CHAOS OR NOT, THERE ARE
68,000 AMERICAN TROOPS WHO ARE
RISKING THEIR LIVES RIGHT HERE
IN THIS COUNTRY TONIGHT.
MANY OF THEM ARE GOING TO BE
SEPARATED FROM THEIR FAMILY AND
FRIENDS FOR AS LONG AS 15
MONTHS, SERVING THEIR COUNTRY,
BEFORE THEY GO HOME.
IT'S A HARD AND STRESSFUL
SITUATION.
THERE IS SO MUCH SACRIFICE.
BUT AS WE LEARNED FROM THE BURNT
FAMILY, IT IS SOMETHING THAT
FAMILIES AT HOME LEARN TO DEAL
WITH.
McKENZIE BURNT KNOWS WHAT IT
MEANS THE TO MAKE SACRIFICES FOR
YOUR COUNTRY.
HER HUSBAND IS SERVING IN THE
SECOND STRIKER BRIGADE IN
AFGHANISTAN.
THIS WILL BE HIS THIRD CHRISTMAS
AT WAR.
>> MOST PEOPLE TAKE FOR GRANTED
THEIR HUSBANDS COMING HOME AT
5:00 AT NIGHT OR BEING HOME ON
THE WEEKENDS OR BEING THERE FOR
HOLIDAYS AND MILITARY FAMILIES
DON'T GET THAT.
WE DON'T HAVE THAT OPPORTUNITY.
>> Reporter: NOW IN HIS FOURTH
DEPLOYMENT, JOSH IS ON A MISSION
IN KANDAHAR AND HAS BEEN AWAY
FROM HIS WIFE AND TWO CHILDREN
FOR SEVEN MONTHS.
>> IT COMES WITH THAT, IT'S
MISSED BIRTHDAYS, ANNIVERSARIES,
FIRST STEPS, CRAWLING.
THEY MISS OUT ON SO MANY THINGS
IN LIFE, THAT ARE JUST
MILESTONES.
>> MARRIED AT AGE 20, McKENZIE
SAYS BEING SEPARATED FOR LONG
STRETCHES HAS BEEN ALL SHE'S
EVER KNOWN.
>> THAT'S MY BOOK.
>> Reporter: AND WHILE
5-YEAR-OLD JOSH JR. AND
9-YEAR-OLD HALLEY TALK TO THEIR
DAD ON THE PHONE ALMOST EVERY
DAY FROM THEIR HOME IN PUYALLUP,
WASHINGTON, HALLEY SAYS IT JUST
ISN'T THE SAME.
>> THE MOST THINGS I MISS ABOUT
M, I Y,D,I 3 %RLLWI HWAHE RHT3
NOW3 pI TSERETUALO
BUT YOUANLLN .
&MANSA IS A
>> YES, MA'AM.
THIS IS AN M-WRAP.
IT'S A VEHICLE THAT WE USE, IT
CARRIES ROUGHLY FIVE PERSONNEL.
YOU HAVE THE DRIVER, THE TANK
COMMANDER, WHICH IS A PASSENGER,
AND THE TWO DISMOUNTS IN THE
BACK AND THE FIFTH PERSON WILL
BE, OF COURSE, THE GUNNER, WHO
IS UP TOP.
>> AND WHERE DO YOU SIT?
>> I SIT ON THE T-SEAT, THE TANK
COMMANDER, WHICH IS IN CONTROL,
BASICALLY, OF THE VEHICLE.
AND AS WE GO OUT, YOU KNOW, I'M
IN CHARGE OF CONTROLLING THIS
VEHICLE, WHERE WE'RE GOING, WHAT
THE GUNNER DOES, IF I NEED TO
REACT TO CERTAIN THINGS, AND I'M
BASICALLY THE PASSENGER, THE TC
OR SHOTGUN SEAT, IF YOU WANT TO
SAY.
>> SO DO YOU EVER -- I GUESS
I -- DO YOU EVER GET SCARED?
>> I GUESS IT'S ONLY HUMAN
NATURE TO GET SCARED, IN SOME
WAY, SHAPE, OR FORM.
BUT YOU DO IT SO MANY TIMES, YOU
GET USED TO IT IN, IN A WAY.
AND I'VE BEEN TRAINING WITH
THESE PEOPLE SO LONG, WE ALMOST
KNOW WHAT WE'RE GOING TO DO
BEFORE WE DO IT.
AND IT IS SECOND NATURE FOR US
AND IT'S PRETTY EASY AT TIMES.
>> AND YOU SAY IT'S SECOND
NATURE, AND YOU KNOW THESE
PEOPLE BETTER THAN ANYONE IN THE
WORLD.
IS THIS SORT OF LIKE A SECOND
FAMILY TO YOU, IN ANY WAY?
>> THIS IS DEFINITELY MY SECOND
FAMILY.
EVEN AS I CAME INTO THE
MILITARY, MY WIFE, IN GENERAL,
WE KNEW THAT THIS WAS A BIG PART
OF OUR FAMILY.
AND MY WIFE HAS ACCEPTED
EVERYONE THAT I'VE TRAINED OR
BEEN LEADERS OF AND IT IS
DEFINITELY A SECOND FAMILY FOR
ME, DEFINITELY.
>> AND THIS HAS BEEN YOUR CAREER
FROM THE BEGINNING?
>> THIS HAS BEEN MY CAREER FROM
THE BEGINNING.
I'VE BEEN IN 12 YEARS.
AND THIS IS DEFINITELY, WHATEVER
I DO, I EXCEL AT, AND I TRY TO
MAKE THE BEST OUT OF IT, AND
THIS IS DEFINITELY WHAT I'VE
DONE MY WHOLE CAREER.
>> YOU KNOW A LOT OF PEOPLE AT
HOME, THEY WONDER, DID AMERICA
REALLY GET ANYTHING OUT OF THIS
WAR?
WHAT HAVE WE ACCOMPLISHED?
AND YOU'RE HERE EVER DAY, YOU'RE
FIGHTING, YOU'RE PATROLLING HERE
IN KANDAHAR.
WHAT HAVE WE GOTTEN OUT OF THIS?
>> WE'VE GOTTEN QUITE A BIT.
I MEAN, HONESTLY, THE AFGHAN
PEOPLE, EVEN FROM WHAT I WAS
DEPLOYED IN IRAQ IN '03, DURING
THE INVASION, YOU COULD SEE THE
IRAQ PEOPLE AND THE AFGHAN
PEOPLE STARTING TO DO STUFF ON
THEIR OWN.
HAVING MORE FREEDOM AND STUFF
LIKE THAT.
AND THAT IS A BIG THING THAT I
TAKE OUT OF THIS.
IS THEM BEING ABLE TO DO STUFF
ON THEIR OWN, WITHOUT HAVING
SOMEONE, YOU KNOW, TELLING THEM
EXACTLY WHAT THEY HAVE TO DO
EVERY DAY OF THEIR LIVES.
AND I THINK THAT'S FREEDOM AND
STUFF LIKE THAT IS A BIG
ACCOMPLISHMENT FOR ME, BEING
HERE, THIS IS MY FOURTH TIME,
AND SEEING THE GAINS THAT WE
HAVE MADE THROUGHOUT THE YEARS.
>> AND DO YOU THINK, FROM WHERE
YOU SIT, THAT AFGHANISTAN IS
GOING TO BE READY, FOR PEOPLE
LIKE YOU TO GO HOME?
>> YES, I DEFINITELY DO.
I'M GOING ON PATROL WITH THE
PARTNERS.
>> YOU GO OUT WITH THEM, BECAUSE
YOU'RE TRAINING THEM --?
>> EXACTLY.
AND THEY DO THINGS ON THEIR OWN
THAT YEARS AGO THEY WERE NOT
DOING ON THEIR OWN.
THE LOGISTICS PART OF IT AND ALL
THAT STUFF.
THEY ARE SUSTAINABLE BY
THEMSELVES.
>> WE HEAR A LOT, THOUGH, ABOUT
AFGHANS WHO WORK WITH AMERICANS
AND THEN THEY WILL BLOW
THEMSELVES UP AND KILL
AMERICANS.
DO YOU HAVE A FEAR THAT THAT
COULD HAPPEN?
>> IT WOULD BE ALMOST UNHUMAN TO
THINK THAT IN THE BACK OF YOUR
MIND, YOU DON'T WANT TO GET WHAT
WE CALL COMPLACENT, BUT WE'VE
BUILT SUCH A TRUST WITH THESE
GUYS THAT THE IN AND OUT DAYS OF
WORKING WITH THEM, THAT STUFF
JUST GOES TO THE WAYSIDE,
BECAUSE YOU HAVE TO TREAT THEM
AS ONE OF YOUR BROTHERS, WORKING
WITH THEM, AND ONE OF YOUR OWN
SOLDIERS, ALSO.
>> AND YOU'RE ABLE TO DO THAT?
>> TOTALLY FINE, YES.
>> SERGEANT, WHAT MAKES YOU THE
MOST PROUD ABOUT WHAT YOU'VE
DONE HERE?
>> I THINK THE MOST PROUD IS
JUST SEEING THE KIDS, AND THAT
GENERATION THAT ARE GOING TO
HAVE A BRIGHT FUTURE HERE IN
AFGHANISTAN.
THE ELDERS AND STUFF ARE STILL
IN THAT MIND-SET, BUT THE
YOUNGER GENERATIONS, WHAT --
THEY HAVE SOMETHING TO LOOK
FORWARD TO AS THE YEARS PROGRESS
IN THIS COUNTRY, IN AFGHANISTAN,
IS THAT THE SUCCESSES THEY CAN
MAKE, THEY CAN GO OUT AND BE
SOMEONE, RATHER THAN BEING
SECLUDED IN A COUNTRY LIKE THIS,
THEY CAN MAKE LIVES FOR
THEMSELVES, OUTSIDE OF HERE.
>> AND WOULD YOU GO TO ANOTHER
WAR, IF THERE WAS ANOTHER WAR?
THE WAR ON TERROR CONTINUES.
GOES SOMEWHERE ELSE, WOULD YOU
STILL GO?
>> WITHOUT A DOUBT, YES.
THIS IS WHAT I SIGNED UP TO DO
FOR MY COUNTRY.
THERE ARE TWO REASONS WHY I
JOINED THE MILITARY, FOR MY
COUNTRY AND FOR MY FAMILY, TO
SUPPORT MY FAMILY, AND THOSE ARE
TWO THINGS I LOVE THE MOST, SO I
WOULD DEFINITELY.
>> THE TWO THINGS THAT HE LOVES
THE MOST.
AND WHEN HE TALKED ABOUT HIS
FAMILY, HE WAS EMOTIONAL.
THEY ACTUALLY HAD PREPARED A
SPECIAL MESSAGE FOR HIM, THAT WE
WERE ABLE TO PLAY FOR SERGEANT
BERNDT.
AND WE WANTED TO SHOW YOU WHAT
HAPPENED.
>> HI, HONEY.
WE LOVE YOU AND MISS YOU.
WE CAN'T WAIT TO SEE YOU.
WE HOPE THAT YOU HAVE A MERRY
CHRISTMAS AND THAT YOU COME HOME
SOON.
>> HI, DADDY.
I LOVE AND MISS YOU AND HAVE A
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
>> MERRY CHRISTMAS!
LOVE YOU.
BYE!
>> GOOD.
>> THEY MISS YOU.
>> I MISS THEM TOO.
>> AND YOU KNOW, YOUR WIFE WAS
REALLY STRONG.
>> YEAH.
>> SHE --
>> WHAT'S THE HARDEST PART ABOUT
NOT BEING WITH HER?
>> I MEAN, JUST BEING THERE
EVERY DAY, SEEING, YOU KNOW,
THEIR DAILY ROUTINE AND WHAT
THEY DO AND, YOU KNOW, JUST
GOING THROUGH, KIDS COMING HOME
FROM SCHOOL, DOING HOMEWORK, YOU
KNOW, MY SON PLAYING SPORTS AND
STUFF LIKE THAT, AND THINGS MY
DAUGHTER DOES, AND SHE'S JUST
SO, YOU KNOW, OUTGOING AND DOES
THINGS ON HER OWN NOW THAT I
DON'T SEE.
THE BIRTHDAYS, OF COURSE, AND
EVEN THE SMALL THINGS LIKE
MOTHER'S DAY AND FATHER'S DAY.
JUST THINGS BEING AWAY FROM THE
FAMILY.
BUT WE TRY TO DO THE BEST, YOU
KNOW.
BUT WHILE I'M DEPLOYED, YOU
KNOW, SHE KEEPS ME SO IN THE
LOOP AND WE TRY TO DO THINGS
TOGETHER STILL AS A FAMILY, EVEN
THOUGH I'M FAR WAY WAY.
BEING THERE FOR THE KIDS,
SINGING HAPPY BIRTHDAY TO THEM
AND THAT STUFF WHILE THEY'RE
OPENING THEIR PRESENTS AND
STUFF, EVEN THOUGH I'M SO FAR
AWAY IN A DIFFERENT COUNTRY, WE
DEEP THAT BOND TOGETHER UNTIL I
COME HOM
>> YOUR SON, I SAW SOMETHING HE
DID AT SCHOOL, WHERE HE WROTE
ABOUT HOW PROUD HE IS OF YOU,
BECAUSE YOU'RE DEPLOYED AND
YOU'RE SAVING PEOPLE'S LIVES.
>> YEAH, HE CAN BECOME A
STICKLER AND HARDHEADED, BUT I
THINK THAT DEEP DOWN INSIDE, HE
ENJOYS AND FEELS SO APPRECIATIVE
FOR WHAT I DO, AND ESPECIALLY MY
DAUGHTER, HALLEY, TOO.
THEY DEFINITELY KNOW WHAT I'M
DOING AND THEY KNOW THAT I'M
SAFE.
SO THAT'S ALL THAT MATTERS.
>> AND YOU SAID, THE ONE THING
SHE TOLD YOU IS THAT HE WAS
WEARING HIS PACKERS SHIRT.
>> YEAH, YEAH.
I DON'T KNOW IF I EMBEDDED IT IN
HIS HEAD WHEN HE WAS SUCH A
YOUNG KID, ABOUT BEING A PACKERS
FAN, BUT AS SOON AS HE KNEW HE
WAS GOING TO BE ON TV, HE HAD TO
WEAR HIS PACKERS JERSEY.
>> YOU WERE TELLING ME A STORY
ABOUT THE PACKERS WERE PLAYING,
BUT YOU WEREN'T HOME.
>> YEAH, EVERY SUNDAY OR SO,
I'LL CALL AND ASK HIM, AND I'LL
BE LIKE, JOSH, DO YOU KNOW WHO
THE PACKERS ARE PLAYING THIS
WEEK?
AND HE KNOWS TO A T WHO THEY'RE
PLAYING.
AND I'LL ASK HIM IF THEY'RE
GOING TO WIN OR IF THEY'RE GOING
TO LOSE.
AND HE ALWAYS VOTES AGAINST THE
PACKERS FOR SOME REASON.
AND I ASKED HIM, JOSH, WHY DO
YOU ALWAYS VOTE AGAINST THE
PACKERS, AND HE SAID, BECAUSE
YOU'RE NOT HERE, DAD.
AND I GET THAT.
A 5-YEAR-OLD SON --
>> HE MISSES YOU.
HE JUST WANTS YOU THERE.
>> DEFINITELY.
>>> NEXT, MY INTERVIEW with
FAWZIA KOOFI.
THE TALIBAN HAVE REPEATEDLY
THREATENED TO KILL HER.
THEY TRIED TO KILL HER AND HER
TWO LITTLE GIRLS, BUT SHE'S
STILL GOING TO RUN FOR PRESIDENT
OF AFGHANISTAN IN 2014.
HER VIEW OF WHERE THE COUNTRY IS
HEADED AND AN INSPIRATIONAL
MEETING WITH HER TWO DAUGHTERS.
IS NEXT.
ION
IN THE NEW 2013 RAM 1500.
ENGINEERED TO MOVE HEAVEN
AND EARTH.
GUTS. GLORY.
RAM.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS KAREN AND JEREMIAH.
THEY DON'T KNOW IT YET,
BUT THEY'RE GONNA FALL IN LOVE,
GET MARRIED,
HAVE A COUPLE OF KIDS,
[ children laughing ]
MOVE TO THE COUNTRY,
AND LIVE A LONG, HAPPY LIFE
TOGETHER
WHERE THEY ALMOST NEVER FIGHT
ABOUT MONEY.
[ dog barks ]
BECAUSE RIGHT AFTER
THEY GET MARRIED,
THEY'LL FIND
SOME RETIREMENT PEOPLE
WHO ARE PAID ON SALARY,
NOT COMMISSION.
THEY'LL GET
STRAIGHTFORWARD GUIDANCE
AND BE ABLE TO FOCUS ON OTHER
THINGS, LIKE EACH OTHER,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
TRY RUNNING FOUR.NING
A RESTAURANT IS HARD,
FORTUNATELY WE'VE GOT INK.
IT GIVES US 5X THE REWARDS
ON OUR INTERNET, PHONE
CHARGES AND CABLE,
PLUS AT OFFICE SUPPLY STORES.
REWARDS WE PUT RIGHT
BACK INTO OUR BUSINESS.
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
WE'VE EVER WANTED TO DO
AND INK HELPS US DO IT.
MAKE YOUR MARK
WITH INK FROM CHASE.
>>> FAWZIA KOOFI IS THE FIRST
WOMAN ELECTED TO AFGHANISTAN'S
PARLIAMENT.
HER STORY IS AN AMAZING ONE AND
AN SPIRING ONE AND SHE IS NOW
CAMPAIGNING FOR THE PRESIDENCY
OF AFGHANISTAN.
SHE HAS LONG BEEN A TARGET OF
THE TALIBAN.
SHE WAS ONCE ATTACKED WITH HER
TWO DAUGHTERS.
SHE WAS SHOT AT IN A CAR AS THEY
DROVE THROUGH AFGHANISTAN.
IN FACT, SO OFTEN SHE RECEIVED
THREATS THAT SHE ACTUALLY NOW
WRITES LETTERS TO HER DAUGHTERS
EVERY TIME BEFORE SHE GOES AWAY
ON A BUSINESS TRIP, JUST IN CASE
SHE DOESN'T MAKE IT HOME.
I VISITED KOOFI IN HER HOME AND
I STARTED BY ASKING HER IF SHE
EVEN FELT SAFE THERE.
>> LIVING IN AFGHANISTAN, YOU
NEVER KNOW WHERE YOU'RE SAFE.
BECAUSE YOU MIGHT BE ATTACKED IN
YOUR HOME.
THIS IS SOMETHING THAT HAPPENED
TO THE POLITICIANS BEFORE.
THEY WERE EVEN ATTACKED IN THEIR
MEETING ROOMS AND THEY WERE
KILLED.
>> IN THE ROOM THAT WE'RE
SITTING RIGHT NOW IS WHERE, IS
PART OF THE WAY AFGHANISTAN
GOVERNS DIFFERENTLY, MAYBE THAN
THE UNITED STATES.
PEOPLE COME FROM YOUR PROVINCE,
THEY COME AND THEY ASK YOU FOR
THINGS.
>> YES.
>> AND EVEN LAST WEEK, YOU SAID
YOU HAD A SCARE, SOMEONE THAT
WAS COMING AND ASKING YOU FOR
HELP, BUT YOU THOUGHT THEY MIGHT
BE WEARING A SUICIDE VEST.
>> SOMETIMES PEOPLE COME WITH
VERY UNUSUAL AND EXCEPTIONAL
SITUATION AND THEY WANT TO PROVE
THAT THEY NEED REALLY OUR HELP.
SO FOR INSTANCE, LAST WEEK, THIS
MAN CAME WHO WAS A PATIENT, WHO
WAS A SICK PERSON.
HE NEEDED TO CHANGE HIS KIDNEYS
AND THE CURRENT KIDNEY DOESN'T
WORK, SO HE WANTED ME TO HELP
HIM TO GET TO THE MINISTER OF
HEALTH.
AND AS HE ENTERED, HE LOOKED SO
UNUSUAL THAT THE ROOM WAS FULL
OF PEOPLE, AND I HAD TO GO -- I
HAD TO RUN ALMOST TO THE OTHER
SIDE OF THE ROOM, THINKING THAT
HE'S FULL OF WIRE AND ALL OF
THOSE EXPLOSIVES.
BUT THEN I REALIZED THAT HE IS A
SICK PERSON, ASKING FOR MY HELP.
THAT'S AN INDICATION OF HOW
PEOPLE OF AFGHANISTAN HAVE
PROBLEMS AND HOW MUCH, BY DOING
SMALL THINGS FOR THEM, THEY
BECOME HAPPY AND THAT'S OUR JOB
TO DO SMALL THINGS.
>> AS A WOMAN, DO YOU THINK A
LOT OF THE, SOME OF THE
INAB TE N RLME PED3
INTOE OL BK  G
THSOH,NDECTL YOU ARE
WORLD, THE OUTSIDE WORLD, WOULD
THEY DEFINE YOU AS CORRUPT,
EVERY MEMBER OF PARLIAMENT
CORRUPT, GIVEN THESE OVERALL
NUMBERS THAT WE SEE?
ARE WE MISSING SOMETHING?
>> I THINK, YES.
WELL, 20% OF THE FANS WHO ARE
COMING TO THE GOVERNMENT OF
AFGHANISTAN, 80% ARE BEING SPENT
THROUGH THE INTERNATIONAL
ORGANIZATIONS.
SO NOT ONLY IN THE BROADER
PICTURE AS THE GOVERNMENT OF
AFGHANISTAN, ALTHOUGH I AM NOT
IN POWER, IN A WAY THAT I AM NOT
IN POSITION, WE ARE THE CRITICS
OF THE GOVERNMENT, WE ARE
REFORMISTS, WE WOULD LIKE TO
BRING CHANGES.
I AGREE IN A WAY THAT THERE IS
CORRUPTION.
NOT ONLY MONEY CORRUPTION, BUT
ALSO POLITICAL CORRUPTION,
ADMINISTRATIVE CORRUPTION.
ALL OF THAT IS THERE.
>> FAWZIA HAS TWO YOUNG
DAUGHTERS.
THEY WERE BEAUTIFUL, SMART,
INSPIRING GIRLS AND I WAS CURE
ABOUT HOW SHE FELT ABOUT THEM
STAYING HERE IN AFGHANISTAN.
IF THE TALIBAN COMES BACK.
SO, FAWZIA, YOU WANT YOUR
DAUGHTERS TO STAY AFTER U.S.
LEAVES.
STAY IN AFGHANISTAN.
>> THEY WILL STAY HERE.
BUT IF THINGS, GOD FOR BID, IF
THINGS GO REALLY BAD, I THINK
THAT WE WILL HAVE NO OPTION.
>> WHAT DO YOU THINK?
WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN WHEN THE
U.S. LEAVES?
>> Translator: THIS IS OUR
COUNTRY AND WE CANNOT LET OUR
COUNTRY GET DOWN.
WHATEVER HAPPY NEED TO STAY IN
MY COUNTRY.
WN U OWP?3
SETESEOE COME WI
DEF E OMTHKI TT
HE'S FULL OF WIRE AND ALL OF
THOSE EXPLOSIVES.
BUT THEN I REALIZED THAT HE IS A
SICK PERSON, ASKING FOR MY HELP.
THAT'S AN INDICATION OF HOW
PEOPLE OF AFGHANISTAN HAVE
PROBLEMS AND HOW MUCH, BY DOING
SMALL THINGS FOR THEM, THEY
BECOME HAPPY AND THAT'S OUR JOB
TO DO SMALL THINGS.
>> AS A WOMAN, DO YOU THINK A
LOT OF THE, SOME OF THE
ACHIEVEMENTS THAT HAVE HAPPENED,
GIRLS GOING TO SCHOOL AND MORE
WOMEN WORKING, WOMEN LIKE YOU,
BEING ABLE TO BE IN PARLIAMENT
NOW, YOU'VE GOT MORE WOMEN IN
PARLIAMENT, 27% OR 22, IT'S ONLY
18% IN THE U.S., SO IT'S BEEN
REAL PROGRESS.
DO YOU THINK A LOT OF THAT IS
GOING TO BE ROLLED BACK OR GO
AWAY WHEN THE U.S. LEAVES, OR DO
YOU THINK AFGHANISTAN WILL KEEP
THAT?
>> WE ARE WORRIED THAT PERHAPS
IN MANY PLACES, TALIBAN CLOSED
SCHOOLS FOR GIRLS, ESPECIALLY IN
THE SOUTH, AND RECENTLY, YOU ARE
AWARE OF THE SCHOOLGIRLS,
ESPECIALLY IN NORTH AND
NORTHEAST, BEING POISONED BY
TALIBAN.
SO WE KNOW THEIR INTENTION.
AND WE ARE WORRIED THAT ONCE THE
INTERNATIONAL COMMUNITY LEAVES,
ALL OF THOSE THINGS THAT HAVE
COME AFTER, AS AN ACHIEVEMENT OF
THE 2001, WOULD BE UNDERMINED BY
SECURITY AND BY THE SYMPATHY TO
BRING TALIBAN BACK TO POWERS.
>> AND ARE YOU GOING TO RUN FOR
PRESIDENT?
I KNOW PEOPLE SAY, LOOK, IT'S A
LONG SHOT.
YOU DON'T HAVE MUCH OF A CHANCE,
BUT ARE YOU GOING TO DO IT
ANYWAY AND GO OUT WITH THE
PUBLIC SPEECHES?
THERE'S OBVIOUSLY RISK TO THAT,
BUT IS IT SOMETHING THAT YOU'RE
DETERMINED TO DO?
>> I DON'T WANT BUY THIS
ARGUMENT, WHEN PEOPLE SAY, THERE
IS NO CHANCE.
IT'S JUST THE MIND-SET, IF A
WOMAN HAS A CHANCE IN OTHER
NEIGHBORING MUSLIM COUNTRIES OF
AFGHANISTAN, WHY NOT IN
IRAED79N RRTI IpEFU  CRU, 3 %ERN
VE,  A  RRTI IpEFU  CRU, 3 %ERN
IPINGIR A IASURE
COUNTRY AND WE CANNOT LET OUR
COUNTRY GET DOWN.
WHATEVER HAPPY NEED TO STAY IN
MY COUNTRY.
>> AND WHAT DO YOU WANT TO BE
WHEN YOU GROW UP?
>> Translator: A PRESIDENT.
>> YOU WANT TO BE THE PRESIDENT?
>> YEAH.
>> PRESIDENT OF AFGHANISTAN?
>> WHAT ABOUT YOU?
>> I WANT TO BE A SPACE
ENGINEER.
>> SPACE ENGINEER.
>> YES.
>> SO PEOPLE WHO SAY, GIRLS IN
AFGHANISTAN ARE GOING TO HAVE
BIG PROBLEMS, MAYBE THEY DON'T
KNOW ABOUT YOU.
>> YES, MAYBE.
>> AND WHAT ABOUT -- WHAT ARE
YOUR WORRIES ABOUT SCHOOL?
DO YOU THINK THAT IT'S GOING TO
BE THE SAME NEXT YEAR WHEN THE
U.S. LEAVES, THAT YOU WILL BE
ABLE TO STAY IN SCHOOL?
ARE YOU WORRIED THERE COULD BE
CHANGES THAT HAPPEN FAST?
>> I THINK THERE COULD BE
CHANGES.
MAYBE TALIBAN COME AGAIN AND
MAYBE NOT.
I DON'T KNOW REALLY.
BUT I HOPE THEY DON'T COME.
>> I KNOW YOU WENT TODAY AND
HEARD YOUR MOM SPEAK.
>> YES.
>> WHAT DID YOU THINK?
>> I THINK SHE REALLY -- SHE WAS
GOOD AND THAT I'M PROUD OF HER.
I'M PROUD OF BEING HER DAUGHTER.
AND THE SPEECH WAS REALLY NICE.
>> THANK YOU, GUYS, VERY MUCH.
>> YOU'RE WELCOME.
>> A SPACE ENGINEER AND
PRESIDENT.
THAT WAS AN INSPIRING MOMENT FOR
ME TO SEE THOSE GIRLS.
AND AS YOU OBVIOUSLY NOTICED,
THEY ARE VERY DEDICATED TO THEIR
EDUCATION.
AND WHEN WE WHERE ARE THERE, WE
SAW THEM UP IN THEIR ROOMS
WORKING.
THEY WERE STUDYING.
AND I THINK IT'S FAIR IT MAKE
SURE THAT EVERYONE AT HOMES
UNDERSTANDS WHAT THAT MEANS,
STUDYING IN 30 DEGREE FAHRENHEIT
WEATHER, NO HEAT, WORKING AND
GETTING READY FOR SCHOOL.
WHEN WE COME BACK, MORE ON
AFGHANISTAN.
TO HELP YOUR PEOPLE, BUT DOES
THIS MEAN THAT EVEN YOU, WHO HAS
BEEN A HERO FOR WOMEN AND
INSPIRATION, A FIGHTER, THE
WORLD, THE OUTSIDE WORLD, WOULD
THEY DEFINE YOU AS CORRUPT,
EVERY MEMBER OF PARLIAMENT
CORRUPT, GIVEN THESE OVERALL
NUMBERS THAT WE SEE?
ARE WE MISSING SOMETHING?
>> I THINK, YES.
WELL, 20% OF THE FANS WHO ARE
COMING TO THE GOVERNMENT OF
AFGHANISTAN, 80% ARE BEING SPENT
THROUGH THE INTERNATIONAL
ORGANIZATIONS.
SO NOT ONLY IN THE BROADER
PICTURE AS THE GOVERNMENT OF
AFGHANISTAN, ALTHOUGH I AM NOT
IN POWER, IN A WAY THAT I AM NOT
IN POSITION, WE ARE THE CRITICS
OF THE GOVERNMENT, WE ARE
REFORMISTS, WE WOULD LIKE TO
BRING CHANGES.
I AGREE IN A WAY THAT THERE IS
CORRUPTION.
NOT ONLY MONEY CORRUPTION, BUT
ALSO POLITICAL CORRUPTION,
ADMINISTRATIVE CORRUPTION.
ALL OF THAT IS THERE.
>> FAWZIA HAS TWO YOUNG
DAUGHTERS.
THEY WERE BEAUTIFUL, SMART,
INSPIRING GIRLS AND I WAS CURE
ABOUT HOW SHE FELT ABOUT THEM
STAYING HERE IN AFGHANISTAN.
IF THE TALIBAN COMES BACK.
SO, FAWZIA, YOU WANT YOUR
DAUGHTERS TO STAY AFTER U.S.
LEAVES.
>> WHAT DO YOU THINK?
WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN WHEN THE
U.S. LEAVES?
>> Translator: THIS IS OUR
COUNTRY AND WE CANNOT LET OUR
COUNTRY GET DOWN.
WHATEVER HAPPY NEED TO STAY IN
MY COUNTRY.
>> AND WHAT DO YOU WANT TO BE
WHEN YOU GROW UP?
>> Translator: A PRESIDENT.
>> YOU WANT TO BE THE PRESIDENT?
>> YEAH.
>> PRESIDENT OF AFGHANISTAN?
>> WHAT ABOUT YOU?
>> I WANT TO BE A SPACE
ENGINEER.
>> SPACE ENGINEER.
>> YES.
>> SO PEOPLE WHO SAY, GIRLS IN
AFGHANISTAN ARE GOING TO HAVE
BIG PROBLEMS, MAYBE THEY DON'T
KNOW ABOUT YOU.
>> YES, MAYBE.
>> AND WHAT ABOUT -- WHAT ARE
YOUR WORRIES ABOUT SCHOOL?
DO YOU THINK THAT IT'S GOING TO
BE THE SAME NEXT YEAR WHEN THE
U.S. LEAVES, THAT YOU WILL BE
ABLE TO STAY IN SCHOOL?
ARE YOU WORRIED THERE COULD BE
CHANGES THAT HAPPEN FAST?
>> I THINK THERE COULD BE
CHANGES.
MAYBE TALIBAN COME AGAIN AND
MAYBE NOT.
I DON'T KNOW REALLY.
BUT I HOPE THEY DON'T COME.
>> I KNOW YOU WENT TODAY AND
HEARD YOUR MOM SPEAK.
>> YES.
>> WHAT DID YOU THINK?
>> I THINK SHE REALLY -- SHE WAS
GOOD AND THAT I'M PROUD OF HER.
I'M PROUD OF BEING HER DAUGHTER.
AND THE SPEECH WAS REALLY NICE.
>> THANK YOU, GUYS, VERY MUCH.
>> YOU'RE WELCOME.
>> A SPACE ENGINEER AND
PRESIDENT.
THAT WAS AN INSPIRING MOMENT FOR
ME TO SEE THOSE GIRLS.
AND AS YOU OBVIOUSLY NOTICED,
THEY ARE VERY DEDICATED TO THEIR
EDUCATION.
AND WHEN WE WHERE ARE THERE, WE
SAW THEM UP IN THEIR ROOMS
WORKING.
THEY WERE STUDYING.
AND I THINK IT'S FAIR IT MAKE
SURE THAT EVERYONE AT HOMES
UNDERSTANDS WHAT THAT MEANS,
STUDYING IN 30 DEGREE FAHRENHEIT
WEATHER, NO HEAT, WORKING AND
GETTING READY FOR SCHOOL.
WHEN WE COME BACK, MORE ON
AFGHANISTAN.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Let's talk about
low-cost investing.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
At Schwab, we're committed
to offering you
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
low-cost investment options--
like our Exchange
Traded Funds, or ETFs
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
which now have the lowest
operating expenses
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
in their respective
Lipper categories.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Lower than SPDR
and even lower than Vanguard.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
That means with Schwab,
your portfolio has
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
a better chance to grow.
And you can trade
all our ETFs online,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
commission-free, from your
Schwab account.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
So let's talk about
saving money,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
with Schwab ETFs.
Schwab ETFs now have the lowest
operating expenses
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
in their respective
Lipper categories.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Call 1-800-4SCHWAB
or visit Schwab.com
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
to open an account today.
Funding is easy
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
with Schwab Mobile Deposit.
Investors should consider
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
carefully information
D#: 1-800-345-2550
contained in the prospectus,
cluding investment objectives,
D#: 1-800-345-2550
risks, charges, and expenses.
You can obtain
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
a prospectus by visiting
D#: 1-800-345-2550
w.schwab.com/schwabetfs.
Please read the prospectus
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
carefully before investing.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
WHY THEY HAVE A
RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
TONIGHT OUR GUEST,
THOMAS SARGENT.
NOBEL LAUREATE
IN ECONOMICS,
AND ONE OF THE MOST CITED
ECONOMISTS IN THE WORLD.
PROFESSOR SARGENT,
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT CD RATES WILL
BE IN TWO YEARS?
NO.
IF HE CAN'T, NO ONE CAN.
THAT'S WHY ALLY HAS
A RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
ALLY BANK.
YOUR MONEY NEEDS AN ALLY.
>>> FOR MOST AMERICANS,
AFGHANISTAN IS A COUNTRY THAT'S
SYNONYMOUS WITH THE WORD AL
QAEDA, THE WORD WAR, THE WORD
TERRORISM, WITH OSAMA BIN LADEN.
BUT THIS IS ALSO A COUNTRY WITH
AN INCREDIBLE HISTORY, AN
INCREDIBLE CULTURE, AND WE AT
OUTFRONT HAVE A SPECIAL
CONNECTION HERE.
ONE OF OUR COLLEAGUES, A
PUBLICIST HERE AT CNN LIVED IN
KABUL IN THE 1970s AND I SPENT
SOME TIME WITH HER FATHER
TALKING ABOUT HIS LIFE HERE WHEN
AFGHANISTAN WAS A TOTALLY
DIFFERENT PLACE.
IN THE 1960s AND '70s,
AFGHANISTAN WAS A CULTURAL
HOTBED, ATTRACTING THE LIKES OF
JAZZ GREATS DUKE ELLINGTON AND
DAVE BRUBECK.
>> DAVE WAS IN KABUL, AND HE HAS
COMPOSED A BEAUTIFUL PIECE.
>> AS AN OFFICIAL IN THE
MINISTER OF CULTURE AND
INFORMATION, 77-YEAR-OLD FAIZ
EXPERIENCED KABUL IN ITS HEYDAY
WITH HIS WIFE AND TWO CHILDREN.
>> OUR HOUSE WAS A PLACE WHERE
ALL THE ARTISTS, INTELLECTUALS
FROM ALL OVER THE WORLD, WOULD
BE WELCOMED AND AFGHAN
COUNTERPARTS WOULD BE INVITED TO
EXCHANGE IDEAS, TO LAUGH.
>> YOU HAD THE SALON OF KABUL.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> BUT IN 1978, FAIZ AND HIS
FAMILY FLED THE COUNTRY AFTER
REVOLUTION AND THE SOVIET
INVASION.
>> IT SADDENS ME THAT ON THE
SPOT THAT I HAD BUILT A STAGE
FOR DUKE ELLINGTON TO PERFORM IS
THAT AWFUL FOOTAGE PLAYED ALL
OVER THE WORLD OF A WOMAN BEING
IN THE BLUE BEING EXECUTED.
>> THE SOCCER STADIUM ONCE
HOSTED PRESIDENTS AND
DIGNITARIES BUT BECAME AN ARENA
FOR PUBLIC EXECUTIONS.
UNDER THE TALIBAN.
MORE RECENTLY SOCCER HAS
RETURNED BUT AFTER MORE THAN 30
YEARS OF WAR AND OPPRESSION,
FAIZ SAYS KABUL IS NOT WHAT IT
ONCE WAS.
FOUR YEARS AGO HE WENT BACK AND
FOUND HIS ONCE PALATIAL
RESIDENCE BOMBED OUT, STRIPPED.
>> WHEN YOU FIRST WENT BACK AND
SAW WHAT HAPPENED, WHAT WAS THAT
MOMENT LIKE?
>> IT WAS A VERY, VERY SAD
MOMENT.
>> HIS HOUSE HAS SINCE BEEN TORN
DOWN AND TURNED INTO A WEDDING
HALL.
THROUGHOUT THE CITY, COUNTLESS
HOMES AND HISTORICAL MONUMENTS
HAVE BEEN DESTROYED.
THE MINUET OF ENLIGHTENMENT.
THERE'S A SMALL SIGN OF HOPE FOR
THE FUTURE OF AFGHANISTAN.
>> I'M HOPING THAT SOME DAY
MAYBE MY CHILDREN, THEIR
CHILDREN WOULD BE LIKE ALL THE
OTHER MINORITIES WHO HAVE COME
TO AMERICA, LIKE ITALIANS OR
GREEKS OR IRISH OR ANYBODY, THAT
THEY'LL GO TO THE OLD COUNTRY
JUST TO SEE THEIR ROOTS.
SOME DAY I HOPE THAT WILL
HAPPEN.
>> TOMORROW NIGHT ON "OUTFRONT"
MORE OF MY EXCLUSIVE INTERVIEW
WITH THE DEFENSE SECRETARY, LEON
PANETTA.
WE TALKED ABOUT IRAN.
HE HAD SOME SURPRISING COMMENTS
ON IRAN'S PURSUIT OF A NUCLEAR
WEAPON AND HE ALSO TALKED ABOUT
THE GERA