>>> BOTTOM OF THE HOUR NOW, 7:30
A.M. EASTERN TIME IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WELCOME, AND WELCOME TO OUR
INTERNATIONAL VIEWERS JOINING US
FROM AROUND THE WORLD.
I'M ALI VELSHI, YOU'RE WATCHING
CNN'S SPECIAL COVERAGE OF THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTING.
WE ARE LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW THIS MORNING
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
IN ABOUT 30 MINUTES WE EXPECT
AUTHORITIES TO HOLD A NEWS
CONFERENCE RIGHT WHERE I AM AND
RELEASE THE IDENTITIES OF THE
VICTIMS.
POLICE SAY 20 CHILDREN BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 WERE KILLED
AS WELL AS SIX ADULTS AT THE
SCHOOL INCLUDING THE PRINCIPAL
AND PSYCHOLOGIST.
SOURCES SAY ADAM LANZA WAS ARMED
WITH THREE GUNS, TWO ON HIM, ONE
FOUND IN A CAR NEARBY.
POLICE SAY HE GOT THE GUNS FROM
HIS MOTHER WHO OWNED THEM.
SHE WAS LICENSED TO HAVE THEM.
SHE WAS FOUND DEAD IN HER HOME
ABOUT 2 1/2 MILES FROM WHERE I
AM NOW.
EVERY NEW DETAIL HELPED PAINT A
PICTURE OF A HORRIFYING TRAGEDY.
CNN'S ANDERSON COOPER EXPLAINS
HOW IT UNFOLDED MOMENT BY
MOMENT.
>> ALL UNITS, THE INDIVIDUAL I
HAVE ON THE PHONE IS CONTINUING
TO HEAR WHAT HE BELIEVES TO BE
GUN SHOTS.
>> Reporter: THE FIRST WORD WAS
CHILLING.
IT ONLY GOT WORSE.
>> THEY'RE REPORTING MULTIPLE
FATALITIES INVOLVED IN THIS
SHOOTING AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
>> Reporter: WITH EACH NEW
REPORT, THE HORROR DEEPENED.
>> REPORTS SAY THE NUMBER OF
DEAD CLOSER TO 30 THAN TO 20,
AND SADLY, MOST OF THEM ARE
CHILDREN.
>> Reporter: EVERY DETAIL, EVERY
FACT BROUGHT MORE SADNESS.
EACH FRESH PIECE OF INFORMATION
A PART OF THE PICTURE, A SCHOOL,
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADE, A SANCTUARY THAT WAS
SUPPOSED TO BE A PLACE OF SAFETY
TORN APART.
>> SHE HEARD THE INTERCOM CAME
ON THE SCHOOL AND SHE HEARD A
SCREAM AND SHE HEARD A GUN
SHOT -- TWO GUN SHOTS.
AND THEN THE SCHOOL WENT INTO
LOCKDOWN.
>> Reporter: A STUDENT'S TEENAGE
BIG BROTHER DESCRIBING THE
SOUNDS OF A GUNMAN ON THE LOOSE
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
>> ON AND OFF DUTY TROOPERS
RESPONDED TO THE SCHOOL, AND
WITH NEWTOWN POLICE IMMEDIATELY
UPON ARRIVAL ENTERED THE SCHOOL
AND BEGAN A COMPLETE ACTIVE
SHOOTER SEARCH OF THE BUILDING.
>> THEY ARRIVED TO CARNAGE.
THE KILLER SAYS A LAW
ENFORCEMENT SOURCE WITH DETAILED
KNOWLEDGE WAS DRESSED FOR BATTLE
IN BLACK FATIGUES AND ARMED FOR
MASS MURDER WITH TWO PISTOLS AND
A MILITARY-STYLE RIFLE.
IN PARTS OF THE SCHOOL, STUDENTS
WERE TOLD TO HIDE IN CORNERS.
TEACHERS RISKED THEIR OWN LIVES
TO PULL BOYS AND GIRLS TO
SAFETY.
>> I'M SO GRATEFUL TO THE
TEACHER WHO SAVED HIM.
>> YOU THINK THE TEACHER SAVED
HIS LIFE?
>> SHE DEFINITELY DID.
HE HAD BULLETS GOING BY HIM AND
GRABBED HIM AND ANOTHER CHILD
AND PULLED HIM INTO A CLASSROOM.
>> EVENTUALLY THE KIDS WERE
EVACUATED TO A NEARBY FIRE HOUSE
WHERE FRANTIC PARENTS DESCENDED.
>> IT WAS TERRIFYING.
I'M STILL TERRIFIED, STILL IN
SHOCK ABOUT IT ALL.
I STILL DON'T KNOW EVERYTHING
THAT HAPPENED.
I KNOW THERE WERE SOME PEOPLE
MISSING TAKEN TO THE HOSPITAL.
>> HIS SON WAS OKAY, HIS SON'S
TEACHER WAS ALIVE, AS WELL.
20 OTHER CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS
WERE KILLED.
THE DEAD BELIEVED TO INCLUDE
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST
AND THE PRINCIPAL.
POLICE DISCOVERED ANOTHER ADULT
VICTIM, THE GUNMAN'S MOTHER
REPORTEDLY AT HOME IN NEWTOWN.
THE GUNMAN TOO IS DEAD.
POLICE SAY THEY FIRED NO SHOTS.
A TIGHT-KNIT COMMUNITY INCLUDING
A NURSE NEARBY SHOCKED,
DISTRAUGHT.
>> I SEE YOU'VE BEEN CRYING.
>> YES.
>> IS IT BECAUSE WHAT YOU SAW?
>> ONE OF THE COPS SAID IT WAS
THE WORST THING HE'D EVER SEEN
IN HIS ENTIRE CAREER, BUT IT WAS
WHEN THEY TOLD THE PARENTS, ALL
THESE PARENTS WERE WAITING FOR
THEIR CHILDREN TO COME OUT.
THEY'LL THOUGHT THEY WERE, YOU
KNOW, STILL ALIVE.
THERE'S 20 PARENTS THAT WERE
JUST TOLD THEIR CHILDREN ARE
DEAD.
IT WAS AWFUL.
>> AWFUL.
AND LATE TODAY, SPEAKING FOR THE
NATION BUT ALSO AS A FATHER, AN
EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT OBAMA FOUGHT
BACK TEARS.
>> THIS EVENING, MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT
IN AMERICA WILL DO, WHICH IS HUG
OUR CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER
AND WE'LL TELL THEM THAT WE LOVE
THEM.
AND WE'LL REMIND EACH OTHER HOW
DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT.
AND THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT
NOW.
>> Reporter: FOR MORE
INFORMATION ABOUT HOW YOU CAN
HELP THOSE AFFECTED, GO TO
CNN.COM/IMPACT.
SO AS THE MINUTES TICK BY, THE
WEIGHT OF THE SHOOTING TRAGEDY
GOT HEAVIER AND HEAVIER.
FIRST, WORD OF THE SHOOTING AT
THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, THEN THE MAGNITUDE.
REPORTS 26 PEOPLE KILLED, 20 OF
THEM CHILDREN, AGES 5 TO 10
YEARS OLD.
NEWS STRONG ENOUGH TO KNOCK THE
WIND RIGHT OUT OF YOU.
AND FOR MANY OF US, IT REALLY,
REALLY DID.
THAT WAS LIKELY THE SAME CASE
FOR POLICE WHO WERE AT THE
SCENE.
THERE WERE GRIEF COUNSELORS NOT
JUST FOR THE FAMILIES, BUT ALSO
FOR THE FIRST RESPONDERS.
INVESTIGATORS DESPITE THE
SADNESS OF IT ALL HAD TO KEEP ON
DOING THEIR JOBS.
JOINING ME RIGHT NOW IS SECURITY
ANALYST MIKE BROOKS.
FIRST OF ALL, MIKE, I HAVE TO
ASK YOU, HOW DO INVESTIGATORS AT
A SCENE LIKE THIS, HOW DO THEY
DEAL WITH THEIR JOBS WHILE THE
SCOPE OF THE TRAGEDY IS JUST
STARING THEM IN THE FACE?
>> YOU KNOW, JOHN, LAW
ENFORCEMENT, FIRST RESPONDERS,
THEY ARE ALL HUMAN ALSO.
AND MANY OF THEM HAVE YOUNG LIKE
WERE KILLED THERE IN THE SCHOOL.
BUT YOU HAVE TO COMPARTMENTALIZE
THAT AND KNOW THAT YOU ARE THERE
TO DO A JOB.
IT'S VERY, VERY HARD.
IN FACT, WE HEARD THE LIEUTENANT
FROM CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
LIEUTENANT VANCE SAY THEY WERE
GETTING HELP FOR THE FIRST
RESPONDERS FOR THE LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICERS WHO WERE
THERE WHO WERE THE FIRST ONES
IN.
THEY WERE GETTING THEM
PSYCHOLOGICAL HELP.
IF THEY DID NEED IT.
AND I THINK THAT'S IMPORTANT
THEY DO HAVE CRISIS INTERVENTION
TEAMS THERE TO DO ON SCENE
DIFFUSINGS AND TO DO A FULL
STRESS DEBRIEFING SHOULD IT
HAPPEN.
BECAUSE, JOHN, THESE ARE THE
PEOPLE WHILE THEY'RE PROCESSING
THAT SCENE, THEY CAN'T LOOK
AWAY.
>> WALK ME THROUGH THE LOGISTICS
OF WHAT'S BEEN HAPPENING OVER
THE LAST EIGHT HOURS.
WE'VE BEEN SAYING ONE OF THE
TRULY SAD THINGS IS THE BODIES
OF THE KIDS WERE STILL THERE
OVERNIGHT.
THE VICTIMS STILL LYING THERE.
THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER DEAD
BELIEVED TO BE OBVIOUSLY.
IT IS A CRIME SCENE, THOUGH, SO
WHAT ARE INVESTIGATORS LOOKING
FOR AT THIS POINT?
>> THEY ARE LOOKING FOR ANY
LITTLE PIECE OF EVIDENCE THAT
NEEDS TO BE GATHERED.
THEY'RE TAKING PHOTOGRAPHS,
THEY'RE VIDEOTAPING.
THEY'RE DOING DIAGRAMS.
YOU FIGURE YOU HAVE -- A MAJOR
SCENE WITH OVER 26 DEATHS, JOHN.
THAT IS JUST AN UNBELIEVABLE
SCENE.
I'VE WORKED BOMBING SCENES WHERE
THERE HAVE BEEN THOUSANDS OF
PEOPLE INJURED, HUNDREDS OF
PEOPLE KILLED, BUT YOU HAVE
LITTLE KIDS AND, STILL, IT'S
VERY DIFFICULT.
BUT THEY'VE GOT A JOB TO DO.
YES, THE SHOOTER IS DEAD, THE
ALLEGED SHOOTER IS DEAD, IS
THERE ANYONE ELSE INVOLVED IN
THIS?
WE DON'T KNOW FOR SURE.
BUT IT'S THE LAW ENFORCEMENT'S
JOB TO GO IN THERE AND DO A
THOROUGH AND ACCURATE ACCOUNTING
OF EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED.
THERE'S SO MUCH EVIDENCE INSIDE
THAT SCHOOL, OUTSIDE THE SCHOOL
POSSIBLY, HIS CAR.
AND THEN THE IDENTIFICATION OF
THE CHILDREN BECAUSE THEY HAVE
DONE A PRELIMINARY
IDENTIFICATION.
THEY KNOW WHO THESE CHILDREN
ARE.
THE PARENTS KNEW WHO THEY ARE.
THEY HAD LAW ENFORCEMENT
ASSIGNED TO THEM TO KEEP THEM UP
TO DATE.
BUT, BY LAW THEY HAVE TO DO AN
IDENTIFICATION, A THOROUGH -- A
POSITIVE IDENTIFICATION OF WHO
THESE CHILDREN ARE.
AND WE'RE PROBABLY GOING TO HEAR
ABOUT THAT THIS MORNING.
BUT, AGAIN, JUST A TOUGH JOB FOR
LAW ENFORCEMENT, THE FIRST
RESPONDERS, FIRE, EMS, AND THESE
CRIME SCENE TECHNICIANS FROM THE
CONNECTICUT STATE MEDICAL
EXAMINER'S OFFICE WHO HAVE BEEN
IN THERE ALL NIGHT DOCUMENTING
EVERY LITTLE BIT OF EVIDENCE
THEY FIND.
>> SO, MIKE, LET'S REWIND A
LITTLE BIT TO THE MOMENTS AFTER
IT BEGINS TO HAPPEN.
AND WHAT THE POLICE, WHAT THE
FIRST RESPONDERS ARE TRAINED TO
DO.
AND LET ME ASK YOU ABOUT THIS.
BECAUSE PEOPLE HAVE BEEN ASKING
ME ABOUT THIS QUESTION OVER THE
LAST SEVERAL HOURS, EVACUATION
VERSUS LOCKDOWN.
WHAT'S THE RIGHT WAY FOR THE
SCHOOL TO HANDLE IT?
TO GET THE KIDS OUT RIGHT AWAY?
OR IS IT TO STAY IN PLACE AND
GET THEM TO A SAFE PLACE IN THE
CLASSROOM?
>> WELL, THEY TRAIN FOR THESE
THINGS.
WE KNOW THEY HAD THEIR ANNUAL
EVACUATION DRILL BACK IN OCTOBER
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
JOHN.
BUT IT'S WHAT THE SITUATION
DICTATES.
WE'VE HEARD SO MANY STORIES NOW
OF TEACHERS PULLING KIDS OUT OF
THE HALLWAYS AND SHELTERING IN
PLACE, IF YOU WILL, WHILE THEY
WAITED FOR LAW ENFORCEMENT TO
COME, LAW ENFORCEMENT CAME, ONE
TEACHER STILL DIDN'T THINK IT
WAS REALLY LAW ENFORCEMENT ASKED
TO SEE THEIR BADGES, SLID THEIR
BADGE UNDER THE DOOR.
AND THEY SAID IF YOU REALLY ARE
LAW ENFORCEMENT, YOU CAN OPEN
THE DOER WITH THE KEY, THEY DID
AND GOT THE CHILDREN OUT.
I WAS LISTENING, JOHN, YESTERDAY
TO THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
FREQUENCY WHILE ALL THIS WAS
HAPPENING, WHILE UNITS WERE
RESPONDING TO THE SCENE AND HAVE
BEEN LISTENING TO SOME OF THE
FIRST UNITS FROM NEWTOWN POLICE
THAT WERE THERE.
AND, YOU KNOW, YOU TRAIN FOR AN
ACTIVE SHOOTER SCENARIO, BUT YOU
HOPE YOU NEVER HAVE TO USE IT.
BUT SOUNDS, JOHN, THAT THESE
FIRST RESPONDERS, THE LAW
ENFORCEMENT, WHEN THEY WENT IN,
THEY KNEW EXACTLY WHAT THEY HAD
TO DO.
AND THEIR JOB WAS TO MAKE SURE
THESE KIDS WERE SAFE, THAT THESE
KIDS WERE EITHER HUNKERED DOWN,
BUT THEY WERE GOING AFTER THAT
GUNMAN.
AND TRY TO NEUTRALIZE THIS
PERSON.
BUT WE HEARD THAT LAW
ENFORCEMENT DID NOT FIRE A SHOT.
BUT THE COORDINATION BETWEEN LAW
ENFORCEMENT, FIRE, AND EMS
SOUNDED LIKE IT WAS TEXTBOOK.
EVEN THOUGH THERE WERE SO MANY
VICTIMS INSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
>> MIKE BROOKS, THANK YOU SO
MUCH FOR BEING WITH US THIS
MORNING.
THE INVESTIGATION INTO THIS OR
HORRIFIC SCENE, THIS AWFUL
TRAGEDY, IT DOES CONTINUE.
>>> MEANWHILE, SHE IS BEING
REMEMBERED AS CARING, SOMEONE
WHO LOVED HER STUDENTS, MORE ON
THE PRINCIPAL WHO LOST HER LIFE
IN THIS TRAGIC CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
BUT FIRST, WHILE INVESTIGATORS
FAMILIES AND THE NATION TRY TO
MAKE SENSE OF THIS ENTIRE
SITUATION, WE WILL BE TALKING
ABOUT THE VICTIMS, THE VICTIMS
OF THIS TRAGEDY, WHO THEY ARE,
AND WE'LL PIECE TOGETHER SOME
MOMENTS OF THEIR LIVES.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
>> THIS IS A VERY, VERY TRAGIC,
TRAGIC SCENE FOR EVERYBODY.
CERTAINLY OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN
FOR THE FAMILIES HERE.
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, ABOUT 9:30,
9:40, WE HEARD NOISES, AND THE
ANNOUNCEMENT SYSTEM WAS STILL
ON, SO IT DIDN'T GO OFF.
YOU COULD HEAR WHAT SOUNDED LIKE
POPS, GUN SHOTS.
>> HER TEACHER MANAGED TO TAKE
TWO CHILDREN OUT OF THE HALLWAY.
PULL THEM INTO THE CLASSROOM,
LOCK THE DOOR AND MOVE EVERYBODY
TO THE OTHER SIDE OF THE ROOM.
>> WE JUST TOLD THE LITTLE BOY
ABOUT HIS SISTER NOW.
WHO AM I GOING TO PLAY WITH, HE
SAID?
I HAVE NOBODY TO PLAY WITH NOW.
EXCUSE ME.
>> WHEN YOUR FIRST GRADER GOES
TO BED AND SAYS, MOMMY, IS
ANYONE FROM MY CLASS LAST YEAR?
ARE THEY ALL OKAY?
AND YOU LOOK AT THEM AND SAY I'M
NOT REALLY SURE.
>> YOU CAN NEVER BE PREPARED FOR
THIS KIND OF INCIDENT.
WHAT HAS HAPPENED, WHAT HAS
TRANSPIRED AT THAT SCHOOL
BUILDING WILL LEAVE A MARK ON
THIS COMMUNITY AND EVERY FAMILY
IMPACTED.
JAYMI'S CHRISTMAS SHOPPING
AND WAS LOOKING FOR
GIFTS AT BEST BUY.
YOU WANNA SEE IF WALMART HAS
SIMILAR GIFTS FOR LESS?
YEAH.
LET'S GO.
SAMSUNG GALAXY S3 --
OVER FIFTY DOLLARS LESS
THAN BEST BUY!
WOW! FIFTY BUCKS!
YEAH!
THAT'S A PAIR OF SHOES.
SEE FOR YOURSELF IF YOU COULD
SAVE ON THE GIFTS YOU WANT.
WALMART.
SEE FOR YOURSELF IF YOU COULD
SAVE ON THE GIFTS YOU WANT.
I HAVE OBLIGATIONS. CUTE
TOBLIGATIONS, BUT OBLIGATIONS.G.
I NEED TO RETHINK THE
CORE OF MY PORTFOLIO.
WHAT I REALLY NEED IS SLEEP.
INTRODUCING THE ISHARES CORE,
BUILDING BLOCKS FOR THE
HEART OF YOUR PORTFOLIO.
FIND OUT WHY 9 OUT OF 10
LARGE PROFESSIONAL INVESTORS
CHOOSE ISHARES FOR THEIR ETFS.
ISHARES BY BLACKROCK.
CALL 1-800-ISHARES FOR A
PROSPECTUS WHICH INCLUDES
INVESTMENT OBJECTIVES,
RISKS, CHARGES AND EXPENSES.
READ AND CONSIDER
IT CAREFULLY
BEFORE INVESTING.
RISK INCLUDES POSSIBLE
LOSS OF PRINCIPAL.
IS THE SAME FREQUENT HEARTBURN
TREATMENT AS PRILOSEC OTC.
NOW WITH A FANCY COATING
THAT GIVES YOU A BURST
OF WILDBERRY FLAVOR.
NOW WHY MAKE A FLAVORED
HEARTBURN PILL?
BECAUSE THIS IS AMERICA.
AND WE DON'T JUST
MAKE THINGS YOU WANT,
WE MAKE THINGS YOU
DIDN'T EVEN KNOW YOU WANTED.
LIKE A SPOON FORK.
SPRAY CHEESE.
AND JEANS MADE
OUT OF SWEATPANTS.
SO GRAB YOURSELF SOME
NEW PRILOSEC OTC WILDBERRY.
[ Male Announcer ]
ONE PILL EACH MORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBURN.
SATISFACTION GUARANTEED
OR YOUR MONEY BACK.
>>> TO OUR VIEWERS IN THE UNITED
STATES AND AROUND THE WORLD,
THIS IS CNN, WE ARE LIVE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT THIS
MORNING.
THIS SAD SATURDAY MORNING WHERE
AN UNSPEAKABLE TRAGEDY, A SCHOOL
SHOOTING THAT CLAIMED THE LIVE
OF 20 CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS
HAS ROCKED THIS TOWN TO ITS
CORE.
EARLIER I SPOKE WITH THE FATHER
OF ONE CHILD WHO SURVIVED THE
SHOOTING, LISTENED TO WHAT HE
HAD TO SAY TO JOHN BERMAN ABOUT
HIS DAUGHTER IS COPING.
WE'LL HEAR FROM HIM IN A MOMENT.
THE FIRST THING I WANT TO DO,
THOUGH, IS GO TO NICK VALENCIA.
BECAUSE NICK IS WORKING ON
INFORMATION ABOUT THE VICTIMS OF
THIS TRAGEDY.
WE SPENT SOME TIME TALKING ABOUT
THE SHOOTER.
BUT WE ARE REALLY WORRIED ABOUT
THE VICTIMS.
18 CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS WERE
SHOT ON-SITE.
ANOTHER TWO CHILDREN DIED IN
HOSPITAL.
LET'S GO TO NICK VALENCIA AT THE
CNN CENTER IN ATLANTA.
NICK, TWO OF THE ADULTS INSIDE
THE SCHOOL HAVE BEEN IDENTIFIED.
WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT THEM?
>> AS YOU MENTIONED ALL MORNING,
THIS STORY REALLY IS ABOUT THE
VICTIMS.
TWO OF THE NAMES THAT WE KNOW SO
FAR, TWO OF THE ADULTS, SIX
ADULTS WERE SHOT IN ALL, TWO
NAMES THAT WE HAVE BEEN ABLE TO
CONFIRM, DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, SHE
WAS THE PRINCIPAL AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SINCE 2010.
SHE'S DESCRIBED, ALI, AS SOMEONE
YOU WOULD WANT EDUCATING YOUR
CHILDREN.
SORT OF THE TEACHER'S TEACHER.
SHE WAS VERY INVOLVED EDUCATOR,
MEMORABLE FOR HER ENTHUSIASM AND
THAT WONDERFUL SMILE YOU SEE
THERE.
SHE SPENT HER CAREER RISING
THROUGH THE RANKS OF THE
CONNECTICUT EDUCATION SYSTEM,
WORKING IN VARIOUS ELEMENTARY
SCHOOLS, MIDDLE SCHOOLS, AND
HIGH SCHOOLS.
THOSE THAT KNOW HER AND KNEW HER
REMEMBER HER AS SOMEBODY WHO
CREATED AN ENVIRONMENT THAT MADE
YOU FEEL ACCEPTED, MADE YOU FEEL
IMPORTANT.
SHE WAS JUST 47 YEARS OLD, ALI.
AND SHE LEAVES BEHIND TWO
DAUGHTERS AND THREE
STEPDAUGHTERS.
ALSO, ONE OF THE ADULT VICTIMS
WE ARE LEARNING IS MARY
SHERLOCK, 56 YEARS OLD.
SHE WAS THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST
AND HEADED UP THE CRISIS
INTERVENTION PROGRAM FOR THE
SCHOOL.
THOSE THAT KNEW HER SAY SHE WAS
A PERSON THAT PEOPLE WOULD GO TO
IN A TIME LIKE THIS AND NOW THEY
CAN'T TURN TO HER.
SHE'S LOST, PERISHED, ONE OF THE
26 VICTIMS OF THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING IN SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
SHE'S REMEMBERED AS SOMEBODY WHO
WAS AN EXPERT IN PSYCHOLOGY.
SHE HAD HER MASTER'S DEGREE,
ALSO VERY INVOLVED IN THE
COMMUNITY, ALI, WORKED WITH
DISABLED ADULTS IN THE COMMUNITY
THERE IN CONNECTICUT, HER -- SHE
WAS A FAMILY WOMAN, AS WELL.
WE LEARNED A LOT ABOUT HER FROM
SOME PERSONAL POSTS WHERE SHE
WROTE SHE ENJOYED GARDENING,
GOING OUT TO THE THEATER.
SHE ALSO LEAVES BEHIND SOME
FAMILY MEMBERS.
31 YEARS SHE WAS MARRIED TO HER
HUSBAND BILL.
SHE ALSO LEAVES BEHIND TWO
DAUGHTERS, BOTH IN THEIR 20s.
ALI?
>> NICK, I DON'T KNOW IF WE'VE
GOT THE PICTURES AT CNN, BUT
RIGHT NEXT TO ME, WE ARE SETTING
UP FOR THE PRESS CONFERENCE
WHICH SHOULD START IN ABOUT 15
MINUTES OR SO OR LESS.
EVERYBODY'S GETTING READY.
THAT'S WHERE WE'RE EXPECTING --
WE WERE TOLD LAST NIGHT AT 8:00
EASTERN THAT STARTING AT 8:00
THIS MORNING WE WOULD START TO
GET MORE INFORMATION ABOUT THE
VICTIMS.
WE'RE GOING TO BE WAITING ON
THAT AND THAT'S GOING TO KEEP
YOU VERY BUSY WHEN THAT HAPPENS.
WAS ONE OF THE FIRST PEOPLE WE
HEARD FROM YESTERDAY ON CNN WAS
A PARENT WHO WAS WITH BOTH OF
THOSE PEOPLE YOU JUST TALKED
ABOUT IN THE SCHOOL WHEN THE
GUNMAN OPENED FIRE.
WHAT DID THAT PARENT SAY?
>> JUST A TERRIFYING, TERRIFYING
STORY, ALI.
WE UNDERSTAND THAT SOME TIME
AFTER 9:30 THERE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY, THE PRINCIPAL AND
THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST WERE
THERE ALONG WITH THE VICE
PRINCIPAL AND A PARENT WHO CNN
SPOKE TO, AT WHICH POINT THEY
HEARD A LOUD POP, POP, POP,
WHICH, OF COURSE, WAS THE
GUNFIRE FROM THE SUSPECTED
GUNMAN.
THEY WENT INTO THE HALLWAY, ALI,
TO INVESTIGATE WHAT WAS GOING
ON.
BOTH SHERLOCK AND HOCHSPRUNG DID
NOT RETURN.
>> ALL RIGHT, NICK, WE'LL STAY
WITH YOU THROUGHOUT THE COURSE
OF THE MORNING AS YOU LEARN
MORE.
YOU'LL BE WATCHING AS WE WILL
VERY CLOSELY IN JUST A FEW
MOMENTS.
IT'S GOING TO BE A VERY, VERY
IMPORTANT NEWS CONFERENCE
HAPPENING RIGHT NEXT TO ME.
JOHN BERMAN IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WITH ME.
AT THE TOWN SQUARE.
JOHN, THIS IS GOING TO BE
DEVASTATING IN A FEW MINUTES.
BECAUSE THERE ARE MANY IN THIS
TOWN WHO KNOW THEY HAVE THEIR
CHILDREN MANY IN TOWN THAT KNOW
20 CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS WERE
KILLED.
AND SOME TIME AFTER THE NEXT 10
OR 15 MINUTES, THEY'RE GOING TO
HEAR THOSE NAMES AND THAT WILL
OPEN UP A WHOLE NEW SET OF
WOUNDS FOR THIS TOWN, WOUNDS
THAT HAVE HARDLY EVEN HAD A
CHANCE TO START HEALING SINCE
LAST NIGHT.
IT'S GOING TO BE A TOUGH TIME IN
THE NEXT FEW MINUTES, JOHN.
>> I THINK YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY
RIGHT, ALI.
I THINK THOSE NAMES ARE GOING TO
MAKE THIS REALITY ALL THE MORE
PAINFUL FOR THE PEOPLE HERE.
I'M STANDING IN FRONT OF, BY THE
WAY, THE ST. ROSE OF LIMA
CATHOLIC CHURCH WHERE THERE WAS
A VIGIL.
MORE THAN 1,000 PEOPLE IN THIS
COMMUNITY GATHERED HERE TO BE
TOGETHER TO GRIEVE TOGETHER.
SO MANY OF THE PEOPLE HERE KNEW
PEOPLE WHO WERE AT THE SCHOOL,
SO MANY PEOPLE HERE DIRECTLY
AFFECTED BY WHAT WENT ON.
EARLIER I SPOKE TO THE FATHER OF
ONE CHILD WHO SURVIVED THE
SHOOTING.
AND IT WAS A TOUGH CONVERSATION.
LISTEN TO WHAT HE HAD TO TOUGH
CONVERSATION.
LISTEN TO WHAT HE HAD TO SAY
ABOUT HOW HIS DAUGHTER IS COPI
WITH THE SITUATION AND HOW HE
FOUND OUT WHAT WAS GOING ON.
>> SHE'S DOING SURPRISINGLY WELL
AFTER WHAT SHE SAW.
>> HOW DID THIS GO DOWN FOR YOU
YESTERDAY?
WHEN DID YOU FIRST GET WORD THAT
SOMETHING HORRIBLE WAS HAPPENING
AT THE SCHOOL?
WHAT DID THEY TELL YOU AND WHAT
DID THEY ASK YOU TO DO?
>> I WORK AN HOUR-PLUS AWAY AND
MY WIFE CALLED ME TO SAY THERE
WAS A SHOOTING.
SHE HAD ALREADY RUSHED TO THE
SCHOOL TO GET MY DAUGHTER, THEY
MADE THEIR WAY TO THE FIREHOUSE.
I WAS ABLE TO GET TO THE
FIREHOUSE EVENTUALLY AND AT THAT
TIME IT WAS JUST TOO EARLY.
WE HAD NO IDEA ABOUT ALL THE
CHILDREN AND THE FACT OF WHO HAD
DIED.
>> YOU KNEW YOUR DAUGHTER WAS
OKAY, THOUGH, CORRECT?
>> THANK GOD WE KNEW SHE WAS
OKAY AND JUST GAVE HER A BIG HUG
AND JUST GOT HER OUT OF THERE.
>> DECLAN, SO MANY PARENTS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY, INCLUDING
ME, FRANKLY, WANT TO KNOW HOW TO
TALK TO OUR KIDS ABOUT THIS.
OUR KIDS DIDN'T GO THROUGH THIS,
HAS YOUR DAUGHTER ASKS YOU ANY
QUESTIONS ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED?
>> WELL, THAT'S THE VERY
DIFFICULT QUESTION.
YOU KNOW, THIS IS ALL NEW.
SO ALL WE REALLY CAN DO, AND I
THINK IS THE BEST THING, IS TO
BE HONEST AND LET HER KNOW WHAT
WE KNOW.
TRY TO TALK TO THEM AND TRY TO
REINFORCE THAT THE BAD GUY THAT
DID THIS IS GONE FOREVER.
BECAUSE, OF COURSE, ALL THEY ARE
TALKING ABOUT IS NOT WANTING TO
GO TO SCHOOL AGAIN.
BOTH OF MY CHILDREN.
I HAVE A 10-YEAR-OLD WHO WAS IN
ANOTHER SCHOOL ON LOCKDOWN AS
WELL.
AND THEY ARE JUST REALLY, REALLY
FREAKED OUT.
AS YOU CAN IMAGINE.
>> Reporter: ABSOLUTELY.
THEY ARE TALKING TO YOU, THEY
DON'T WANT TO GO BACK TO SCHOOL
AGAIN.
DID YOU DAUGHTER TELL YOU
ANYTHING ABOUT WHAT IT WAS LIKE
TO BE IN THE SCHOOL AS THIS WAS
HAPPENING?
>> SHE WAS IN HER READING CLASS,
AND IT WAS A SEPARATED CLASS
WITH JUST, USUALLY THERE'S JUST
A FEW KIDS IN THERE, AND SHE
HEARD A BUNCH OF BANGING, WHAT
SOUNDED LIKE HAMMERING, SHE
SAID.
AND HER TEACHER, HER READING
TEACHER, GRABBED MY DAUGHTER AS
WELL AS A FELLOW TEACHER THAT
WAS IN THE READING ROOM, AND
ACTUALLY LOCKED THEM IN THE
BATHROOM AND THEY JUST HEARD
LOTS OF SHOTS.
I THINK MY DAUGHTER SAID SHE
HEARD SCREAMING AND EVENTUALLY
THE POLICE WERE BANGING ON THE
DOOR AND WERE ABLE TO ESCORT
THEM INTO THE HALLWAY, GET THEM
OUT TOWARDS, UNFORTUNATELY,
WHERE FROM WHAT I UNDERSTAND,
WHERE MOST OF THE SHOOTINGS
HAPPENED, WHICH IS A PRETTY
ROUGH SCENE FROM WHAT I
UNDERSTAND FROM WHAT MY DAUGHTER
TOLD ME.
AND THEN THEY WERE ABLE TO WHISK
THEM AWAY TO THE FIREHOUSE.
AND I BELIEVE MY DAUGHTER, FROM
WHAT SHE TELLS ME, WAS THE FIRST
KID TO GET TO THE FIREHOUSE.
>> Reporter: THAT WAS DECLAN IS
THE FATHER OF AN 8-YEAR-OLD GIRL
WHO SURVIVED THIS HORRIBLE
EVENT.
HE'S TALKING TO HER AND HIS
10-YEAR-OLD SON WITH SO MANY
QUESTIONS.
THE SADDEST THING I HAVE HEARD
IS THAT HIS KIDS DON'T WANT TO
GO BACK TO SCHOOL.
AS FAMILY AND FRIENDS TRY TO
COME TO GRIPS WITH THIS TRAGEDY,
MANY ARE TURNING TO THEIR FAITH
FOR ANSWERS.
CNN'S ANDERSON COOPER ASKED A
LOCAL CHURCH LEADER HOW HE HELPS
THE PEOPLE IN MOURNING.
>> WHAT CAN YOU REALLY SAY?
MANY OF THEM JUST SAID TO ME,
THANK YOU FOR BEING HERE WITH
US.
WE PRAY TOGETHER, WE HUGGED EACH
OTHER THERE, WERE A LOT OF
TEARS.
CERTAINLY A LOT OF EMOTION.
AND IT HAS NOT REALLY SETTLED
INTO THEIR LIVES THAT THEIR
CHILD HAS BEEN TAKEN FROM THEM.
I MUST SAY FOR THE PARENTS I
SPOKE WITH TODAY THERE WAS A
TREMENDOUS AMOUNT OF LOVE FOR
THESE CHILDREN.
AND I KNOW THE DAYS AHEAD ARE
GOING TO BE VERY DIFFICULT AND
WE AS A COMMUNITY, CERTAINLY AS
A CHURCH COMMUNITY, WILL BE
PRESENT TO THEM.
BUT THE WORDS, WHAT CAN YOU SAY
AT A TIME LIKE THIS?
>> THERE ARE PROBABLY A LOT OF
PARENTS WRESTLING AROUND THE
COUNTRY AND AROUND THE WORLD
RIGHT NOW WITH WHAT ARE THEY
GOING THE SAY TO THEIR CHILDREN
WHO ASK THEM QUESTIONS ABOUT
THIS?
WHAT WILL YOU RECOMMEND FOR
PEOPLE TO SAY TO THEIR KIDS, NOT
KIDS FROM NEWTOWN WHO WERE AT
THE SCHOOL, BUT JUST WHO HEAR
ABOUT THIS AND WANT TO KNOW, ARE
THEY SAFE ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED?
>> I THINK THAT'S THE ONE THING
YOU HAVE TO ENSURE THEM ABOUT.
SOME CIRCUMSTANCES ARE BEYOND
ANY HUMAN CONTROL, BUT WE HAVE
TO TEACH THE CHILDREN TO TRUST.
I KNOW IT'S A DIFFICULT WORLD IN
WHICH WE LIVE AND IT IS VERY
DIFFICULT TO TRUST EVERYONE, BUT
THEY HAVE TO HAVE FAITH.
AND THEY HAVE TO HAVE FAITH IN
GOD AND FAITH IN EACH OTHER.
AND I HOPE THAT THESE PARENTS
WILL CERTAINLY LEARN FROM THIS.
ONCE AGAIN, THE VALUE OF FAMILY
AND KEEP PRIORITIES STRAIGHT.
THE CHILDREN NEED TO KNOW THEY
ARE LOVED AND THEY ARE IN
ENVIRONMENTS THAT CAN BE SAFE
AND AN ENVIRONMENT TO GROW UP TO
BE PRODUCTIVE CITIZENS.
I DON'T KNOW HOW YOU TAKE THE
FEAR OUT OF A CHILD'S HEART
EXCEPT BY LOVE, AND THESE
CHILDREN TODAY WERE CERTAINLY
DEEPLY LOVED BY THEIR PARENTS.
>> ABOUT 1,000 PEOPLE IN THE
NEWTOWN COMMUNITY PACKED THIS
CHURCH FOR A VIGIL INSIDE AND
OUTSIDE.
SOME PEOPLE WERE CRYING THERE,
WERE HUGS AND SO MANY PEOPLE
PRAYING FOR THE LIVES OF THOSE
WHO WERE LOST.
SO MANY OF THE SURVIVORS,
OBVIOUSLY, ARE STILL IN SHOCK
TODAY, BUT AT LEAST ONE OF THE
TEACHERS AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL KEPT HER COOL
EVEN AFTER HEARING THE GUNSHOTS.
JANET BALMER ALSO SPOKE TO
ANDERSON COOPER.
>> ABOUT 9:30, 9:40, WE HEARD
ANNOUNCEMENTS AND THE
ANNOUNCEMENT SYSTEM WAS STILL
ON.
SO YOU COULD HEAR WHAT SOUNDED
LIKE POPS, GUNSHOTS, OF COURSE
I'M NOT GOING TO TELL THAT TO
5-YEAR-OLDS, SO I SAID TO THEM,
WELL, WE ARE GOING OVER TO A
SAFE AREA AND WE ARE GOING TO,
YOU KNOW, WE READ A STORY AND
KEPT THEM CALM.
WE DID A LOCKDOWN DRILL AND
CLOSED THE DOORS, LOCKED AND
COVERED THE WINDOWS, YOU KNOW,
KEPT THE CHILDREN WITH US.
I HAVE OTHER ADULTS IN MY --
>> I FIND THAT AMAZING -- I FIND
THAT AMAZING, FEARING THAT YOU
HEAR GUNSHOTS, YOU WERE ABLE TO
HAVE THE COMPOSURE TO SIT DOWN
TO READ TO YOUR STUDENTS.
I MEAN, THAT'S EXTRAORDINARY.
>> THAT'S WHAT YOU HAVE TO DO
WITH 5-YEAR-OLDS BECAUSE YOU
CAN'T LOSE IT.
I'VE BEEN DOING THIS FOR A LONG
TIME.
IT'S MY 18th YEAR OF TEACHING
AND MY JOB WAS TO KEEP THEM
SAFE.
I DIDN'T KNOW, THERE WAS NO
ANNOUNCEMENT OF WHAT WAS GOING
ON.
MYNSTINCT WAS IT WASN'T GOOD.
WE KEPT THEM CALM AND STAYED IN
THE ROOM UNTIL THERE WAS BANGING
AT THE DOOR UNTIL IT WAS THE
POLICE AND THE TROOPERS AND
WHOEVER WAS THERE.
AND THEY HAD US EXIT THE
BUILDING.
>> Reporter: IT'S OUR JOB TO
KEEP THEM SAFE, SHE SAID.
WE ALSO HEARD FROM ANOTHER
TEACHER INSIDE HER CLASSROOM
DURING THIS AWFUL MORNING.
IN AN INTERVIEW WITH ABC NEWS,
FIRST GRADE TEACHER KAITLIN ROIG
TALKED TO HER STUDENTS.
>> I NEED YOU TO KNOW I LOVE YOU
VERY MUCH AND IT IS GOING TO BE
OKAY.
I THOUGHT WE WERE ALL GOING TO
DIE.
YOU KNOW, I DON'T KNOW IF THAT'S
OKAY.
TEACHERS, I WANT THEM TO KNOW
SOMEONE LOVED THEM AND I WANTED
THAT TO BE ONE OF THE LAST
THINGS THEY HEARD.
NOT THE GUNFIRE IN THE HALLWAY.
IT WAS SO HORRIBLE.
>> Reporter: SO MANY OF US LOOK
TO TEACHERS AS HEROES ALL THE
TIME, FRANKLY, BUT MANY PARENTS
LAST NIGHT WERE THANKFUL FOR THE
BRAVE TEACHERS, ESPECIALLY
THANKFUL FOR HELPING GET THEIR
CHILDREN TO SAFETY.
ONE DAUGHTER SPOKE TO HER MOTHER
ABOUT WHAT IT WAS LIKE INSIDE
THE SANDY HOOK HIGH SCHOOL.
HER MOTHER SHARED THAT STORY
WITH ANDERSON.
>> SHE DID MENTION THAT SHE DID,
OF COURSE, HEAR GUNSHOTS.
THEY WERE ON THE SAME FLOOR.
SHE, HER TEACHER, MANAGED TO
TAKE TWO CHILDREN OUT OF THE
HALLWAY, PULL THEM INTO THE
CLASSROOM, LOCK THE DOOR AND
MOVE EVERYBODY OVER TO THE OTHER
SIDE OF THE ROOM.
IT WAS VERY CONFUSING, AS IT
WOULD BE IN ANY OF THESE CASES,
TO GO AND PICK UP YOUR CHILD
ONCE WE FIGURED OUT THAT
EVERYBODY WAS DISPATCHED TO
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
I WAS ONE OF THE FIRST PARENT
THERE IS ALONG WITH A FRIEND OF
MINE.
WE BOTH FIGURED OUT WHAT WAS
GOING ON AND RAN OVER THERE.
THEY WERE SMART TO GET THEM OUT
OF THE BUILDING AND MOVED THEM
OVER TO THE FIREHOUSE, BUT YOU
COULD SEE MY DAUGHTER'S TEACHER
WAS VISIBLY UPSET AS WELL AS
MANY OF THE CHILDREN THERE.
AND SHE DID A VERY HEROIC THING
AND PULLED TWO KIDS OUT OF THE
HALLWAY AND JUST SHOVED THEM THE
CLASS AND LOCKED THAT DOOR UP.
AND THE KIDS ARE GOING TO SUFFER
FROM