HOURS BEEN GETTING REPORTS
DIRECTLY FROM THE SCENE, AND HE
SAYS CONSISTENTLY THOSE REPORTS
SAY THE NUMBER OF DEAD, CLOSER
TO 30 THAN TO 20, AND SADLY MOST
OF THEM ARE CHILDREN.
>> AND, JOHN, DOES HE HAVE A
SENSE OF WHEN WE MIGHT BE ABLE
TO LEARN EXACTLY WHAT THAT
NUMBER, THAT FINAL NUMBER IS
GOING TO BE?
DOES HE HAVE A SENSE THIS MIGHT
BE HOURS AWAY WE'LL LEARN THIS
NEWS?
>> HE BELIEVES IT WILL BE
SOMETIME THIS AFTERNOON.
HE BELIEVES THEY ARE SETTLED
PRETTY CLOSELY ON A NUMBER AT
THE SCENE, BUT THEY WANT TO DO
TWO THINGS.
NUMBER ONE, HAVE THE GOVERNOR
AND STATE POLICE INFORM THE
FAMILIES AND NUMBER TWO, JUST DO
A SECOND AND A THIRD SWEEP OF
THAT SCHOOL TO MAKE SURE THEY
HAVE LOOKED EVERYWHERE.
>> ALL RIGHT, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH, JOHN, APPRECIATE IT.
WITNESSES AND PARENTS, THEY'RE
STARTING TO TALK ABOUT HOW THIS
IS ALL UNFOLDING.
THEIR OWN EXPERIENCES, REALLY,
THE EMOTIONS JUST POURING OUT
AND YOU CAN'T BELIEVE THE KIND
OF TRAGEDY THEY'RE FEELING.
THESE ARE SOME OF THE FOLKS THIS
IS WHAT THEY'RE TELLING US.
I WANT TO BRING THEM IN.
>> YOU'VE BEEN CRYING.
>> YES.
>> IS IT BECAUSE OF WHAT YOU
SAW?
>> NO, THEY WOULDN'T EVEN LET US
IN THE BUILDING.
ALL I CAN SAY IS THAT ONE OF THE
COPS THAT, YOU KNOW, THE WORST
THING HE HAD EVER SEEN IN HIS
ENTIRE CAREER, BUT IT WAS WHEN
THEY TOLD THE PARENTS, ALL THE
PARENTS WERE WAITING FOR THEIR
CHILDREN TO COME OUT, THEY
THOUGHT THEY WERE, YOU KNOW,
STILL ALIVE.
AND THERE IS 20 PARENTS THAT
WERE JUST TOLD THEIR CHILDREN
ARE DEAD.
IT WAS AWFUL.
>> AND YOU WERE UNABLE TO DO
ANYTHING.
>> RIGHT.
WE KNEW AT ONE POINT THEY ASKED
THE AMBULANCES TO LEAVE, THAT
THEY DIDN'T NEED THEM AND WE
KNEW THAT WASN'T A GOOD SIGN.
>>> I'M WOLF BLITZER IN
WASHINGTON.
WE'RE CONTINUING OUR BREAKING
NEWS COVERAGE OF A DRAMATIC,
HORRIFIC STORY, UNFORTUNATELY,
UNFOLDING IN CONNECTICUT RIGHT
NOW.
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, AT A
SMALL ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
FOR THOSE OF YOU WHO ARE JUST
TUNING IN, WE ARE NOW GETTING
NUMBERS, OUR OWN JOHN KING
REPORTING, QUOTING LAW
ENFORCEMENT SOURCES AS SAYING AT
LEAST 20, BUT PERHAPS CLOSER TO
30 INDIVIDUALS, MANY OF THEM
CHILDREN, HAVE BEEN KILLED IN
THIS INCIDENT.
INDIVIDUAL SUSPECT, A
20-YEAR-OLD, IS -- THE SUSPECT,
THE SHOOTER IS A 20-YEAR-OLD.
LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIAL WITH
KNOWLEDGE OF THE INVESTIGATION
TELLING OUR SUSAN CANDIOTTI,
THAT SUSPECT, WE BELIEVE, IS
DEAD RIGHT NOW.
YOU JUST HEARD POLICE AT A SMALL
BRIEFING, DIDN'T PROVIDE A LOT
OF INFORMATION, BUT THEY DID
TELL US THE AREA NOW APPEARS TO
BE SECURE, BUT THIS HAS BEEN A
HORRIFIC, HORRIFIC MASS KILLING
AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
CONNECTICUT.
A SCHOOL FOR KIDS FROM
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADE.
WE'RE WATCHING ALL OF THIS
UNFOLD.
LISA PROCACHINI IS ON THE PHONE
RIGHT NOW.
SHE'S A PARENT OF AN 8-YEAR-OLD
AT THE SCHOOL, THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
YOUR 8-YEAR-OLD IS FINE, I TAKE
IT, LISA.
TELL US WHAT HAPPENED.
WALK US THROUGH WHAT YOU SAW AND
WHAT YOU HEARD.
>> WELL, I HAD A CALL FROM ONE
OF THE TEACHERS WHO WAS WITH MY
DAUGHTER AT THE TIME.
AND LOCKED THEMSELVES IN A
BATHROOM.
THEY KEPT MY CHILD CALM, AND
TOLD HER IT WAS JUST SOME
HAMMERING GOING ON.
AND THIS IS ALL WHAT MY DAUGHTER
TOLD ME WHAT HAPPENED.
NEXT THING YOU KNOW, THE POLICE
CAME IN AND THEY, I GUESS, KN  K
KNOCKED ON THE DOOR AND LET THE
STUDENTS -- MY DAUGHTER AND HER
TEACHER OUT AND AS MY DAUGHTER
IS WALKING OUT, SHE DID SEE
BLOOD AND GLASS.
AND THAT'S WHAT HER -- AS MUCH
AS SHE SAW, THAT'S WHAT SHE SAW.
AND I GOT A CALL FROM A TEACHER
WHO WAS WONDERFUL ENOUGH TO GIVE
ME A CALL AND LET ME KNOW MY
DAUGHTER WAS SAFE.
>> AND SHE'S HOME WITH YOU RIGHT
NOW.
>> YES.
>> AND HOW IS SHE DEALING WITH
THIS?
I ASSUME THIS HAS BEEN A PRETTY
TRAUMATIC EXPERIENCE FOR HER.
>> I DON'T REALLY THINK SHE GETS
IT RIGHT NOW.
I DON'T -- I DON'T THINK SHE
UNDERSTANDS HOW SERIOUS THINGS
ARE.
I'M KIND OF EVEN NUMB TO THE
FACT OF WHAT HAS GONE ON.
I'M JUST IN A STATE OF SHOCK,
STILL.
SO, YOU KNOW, I THINK TIME WILL
TELL.
I JUST DON'T KNOW HOW I'M GOING
TO HANDLE HAVING HER KNOW ALL
THE, YOU KNOW, THE WHOLE
SITUATION.
SO --
>> YOUR LITTLE 8-YEAR-OLD HAS
BEEN A STUDENT AT THIS SCHOOL,
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
WHAT, SINCE KINDERGARTEN.
SO YOU PRESUMABLY KNEW A LOT OF
THE TEACHERS AND THE PRINCIPAL
AS WELL, RIGHT?
>> YES, I DID.
SHE WAS --
>> TELL US ABOUT THE PRINCIPAL.
>> SHE WAS A WONDERFUL,
BEAUTIFUL PERSON.
SHE'S PRETTY NEW WITH THE
SCHOOL.
AND YOU COULDN'T ASK FOR A
BETTER PRINCIPAL.
SHE'S VERY WARM, AND PERSONABLE.
AND SHE IS ALWAYS MAKING YOU
FEEL COMFORTABLE ABOUT YOUR
CHILD AT THE SCHOOL.
>> DID YOU -- IN YOUR WILDEST
IMAGINATION, AND I KNOW THIS IS
A TOUGH SITUATION, LISA, COULD
YOU EVER IMAGINE A MASS SHOOTING
IN CONNECTICUT IN YOUR SMALL
TOWN, NOT FAR AWAY FROM DANBURY?
DID IT EVER CROSS YOUR MIND
SOMETHING LIKE THIS COULD
HAPPEN?
>> WELL, NO.
BUT, HOWEVER, IT IS HAPPENING SO
MUCH THAT, YOU KNOW, IT IS THOSE
TOWNS THAT YOU WOULD LEAST
SUSPECT IT HAPPENING THAT IT IS
HAPPENING TO.
AND WHY IS IT HAPPENING SO MUCH
AND WHAT ARE WE GOING TO DO IN
THE FUTURE FOR OTHER SCHOOLS?
HOW ARE WE GOING TO STOP THIS?
>> WHAT DO YOU THINK?
WHAT DO WE NEED TO DO?
>> I WISH I KNEW THE ANSWER TO
THAT.
YOU KNOW, JUST HAVING THE
PRINCIPALS, TEACHERS, MORE
AWARE, MORE EQUIPPED PERHAPS
WITH THINGS.
I DON'T -- YOU KNOW, I'D LIKE TO
SEE SOMETHING LIKE THAT TAKE
PLACE.
>> IT IS A HORRIFIC --
>> THE CHILDREN TO BE SAFE.
>> LISA, THANK GOD YOUR LITTLE
GIRL, YOUR 8-YEAR-OLD GIRL IS
OKAY, WITH YOU, AT HOME, LISA
JOINING US ON THE PHONE.
GOOD LUCK DEALING WITH ALL OF
THIS, OBVIOUSLY.
A HORRIFIC, HORRIFIC SITUATION.
JUST A LITTLE WHILE AGO, ONE OF
THE YOUNG STUDENTS AT THE SCHOOL
SPOKE OUT AND SAID THIS.
>> I WAS IN THE GYM AT THE TIME.
AND SO THE TEACHER -- WE HEAR
LOTS OF BANGS AND WE THOUGHT
THAT IT WAS THE CUSTODIAN
KNOCKING STUFF DOWN.
WE HEARD SCREAMING.
AND SO WE -- WE WENT TO THE
WALL, AND WE SAT DOWN AND THEN A
POLICE CAME IN AND IS LIKE, IS
HE IN HERE, AND HE RAN OUT, AND
OUR TEACHER, WHEN SOMEBODY
YELLED GET TO A SAFE PLACE, SO
WE WENT TO THE CLOSET IN THE GYM
AND WE SAT THERE FOR A LITTLE
WHILE.
AND THEN THE POLICE WERE
KNOCKING ON THE DOOR AND
THEY'RE, LIKE, WE'RE EVACUATING
PEOPLE, WE'RE EVACUATING PEOPLE.
SO WE RAN OUT, THERE IS POLICE
AT EVERY DOOR, THEY'RE LEADING
US DOWN THIS WAY, DOWN THIS WAY,
QUICK, QUICK, COME ON.
AND WE RAN DOWN TO THE
FIREHOUSE, AND THERE WAS A MAN
PINNED DOWN TO THE GROUND WITH
HANDCUFFS ON.
AND WE THOUGHT THAT WAS THE
VICTIM.
WE REALLY DIDN'T GET A GOOD
GLANCE AT HIM BECAUSE HE WAS --
THERE WAS A CAR BLOCKING IT.
PLUS WE WERE RUNNING REALLY
QUICK.
SO THEN WE GOT TO THE FIREHOUSE
AND WE SAT IN OUR CLASSES AND WE
WERE ALL REALLY HAPPY THAT WE
WERE ALL ALIVE.
>> HARD TO BELIEVE THIS COULD
HAPPEN IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
NOT FAR FROM DANBURY,
CONNECTICUT, A SMALL ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, A FEW HUNDRED KIDS IN
THERE, KINDERGARTEN THROUGH
FOURTH GRADE.
THE POLICE CHIEF SPOKE TO
REPORTERS A LITTLE WHILE AGO AND
SAID THIS.
>> I WILL GIVE YOU SOME VERY
BASIC AND BRIEF INFORMATION AS
WE KNOW IT NOW.
AND WE WILL SET UP REGULAR PRESS
BRIEFINGS AS APPROPRIATE.
JUST AFTER 9:30 THIS MORNING,
NEWTOWN POLICE RECEIVED A 911
CALL FOR AN EMERGENCY AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
NEWTOWN PD UPON OBTAINING
INFORMATION AS TO THE STATUS OF
THE SITUATION CONTACTED THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE AND
REQUESTED ASSISTANCE FROM STATE
POLICE AND SURROUNDING POLICE
DEPARTMENTS.
ON AND OFF TROOPERS RESPONDED TO
THE SCHOOL AND WITH NEWTOWN
POLICE IMMEDIATELY UPON ARRIVAL
ENTERED THE SCHOOL AND BEGAN A
COMPLETE, ACTIVE SHOOTER SEARCH
OF THE BUILDING.
THAT INCLUDED CHECKING EVERY
DOOR, EVERY CRACK, EVERY
CREVICE, EVERY PORTION OF THAT
SCHOOL.
OUR MAIN OBJECTIVE WAS TO
EVACUATE AS QUICKLY AND AS
EFFICIENTLY AS POSSIBLE ANY AND
ALL STUDENTS AND FACULTY IN THE
SCHOOL.
THE ENTIRE SCHOOL WAS SEARCHED.
THAT WAS ACCOMPLISHED, A STAGING
AREA WAS SET UP, STUDENTS AND
STAFF WERE PUT INTO THAT STAGING
AREA.
AND SOON THERE AFTER THE
CHILDREN WERE -- AND STAFF WERE
REUNITED WITH PARENTS AND LOVED
ONES.
THERE WERE SEVERAL FATALITIES AT
THE SCENE.
BOTH STUDENTS AND STAFF.
THERE IS NO INFORMATION RELATIVE
TO THAT THAT IS BEING RELEASED
AT THIS TIME UNTIL WE MADE
COMPLETE AND PROPER
NOTIFICATION.
THE SHOOTER IS DECEASED INSIDE
THE BUILDING.
THERE IS A GREAT DEAL OF WORK
THAT IS UNDERTAKEN IMMEDIATELY
UPON LOCATING THE SHOOTER AND
THAT IS THERE IS A GREAT DEAL OF
SEARCH WARRANT ACTIVITY, GREAT
DEAL OF LAW ENFORCEMENT
ACTIVITY, IN AND OUT OF STATE,
TO BE SURE WE COVER ALL THE
BASES RELATIVE TO THAT SPECIFIC
INDIVIDUAL.
SUFFICE IT TO SAY THE SCENE IS
SECURE.
THE STATE POLICE MAJOR CRIMES
SQUAD AND NEWTOWN POLICE
DEPARTMENT, DANBURY STATE
ATTORNEY AND MANY AGENCIES ARE
WORKING TOGETHER TO ANSWER ALL
THE QUESTIONS SURROUNDING
EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED.
AS MR. OCCHIOGROSSO SAID, WE'LL
KEEP YOU BRIEFED, WE'LL KEEP YOU
INFORMED ON A REGULAR BASIS,
WE'LL PUT EVERYTHING OUT VIA OUR
WEBSITE AND WITH THE PRESS
CONFERENCES.
>> THAT WAS THE POLICE CHIEF IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
LAW ENFORCEMENT SOURCE CLOSE TO
THE INVESTIGATION TELLS OUR OWN
SUSAN CANDIOTTI THAT THE SUSPECT
WHO IS DECEASED IS A
20-YEAR-OLD.
WE DON'T KNOW THE PRECISE
CONNECTION, THE RELATIONSHIP HE
MAY HAVE HAD WITH THE SMALL
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE ARE WORKING THAT.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI WILL BE JOINING
US MOMENTARILY.
SHE'S WITH US RIGHT NOW.
YOU'RE ON THE SCENE, SUSAN.
UPDATE US ON WHAT YOU KNOW.
>> Reporter: WELL, WOLF, THE
LATEST INFORMATION WE HAVE NOW,
AND I DIDN'T HEAR YOUR EARLIER
REPORTS JUST NOW, BUT IS THAT
THE DEATH TOLL IS NOW RISING.
EARLIER WE HAD HEARD THAT IT WAS
ABOUT 20 PEOPLE, NOW WE'RE
HEARING THE NUMBER OF FATALITIES
OF ADULTS AND CHILDREN IS CLOSER
TO 30.
AND 18 TO 20 OF THOSE DEAD ARE
CHILDREN, WOLF.
WE'RE HEARING ALSO THAT THE DEAD
SHOOTER IN THIS CASE, ALREADY
DEAD, IS SOMEONE IN HIS 20s, WE
DO KNOW ACCORDING TO THE STATE
POLICE, THEY ANNOUNCED THE NEWS
CONFERENCE, THAT THE SEARCH
WARRANT IS BEING EXECUTED AT
THAT SUSPECTED SHOOTER'S HOME.
THE SHOOTER HAS BEEN IDENTIFIED
TO ME BY A SOURCE AS RYAN LANZA,
IN HIS 20s, APPARENTLY, WE'RE
TOLD, FROM THE SOURCE, FROM THIS
AREA HOWEVER THAT HAS NOT BEEN
CONFIRMED BY THE STATE POLICE
WHO DID SAY THAT A SEARCH
WARRANT IS BEING EXECUTED AT
THIS TIME.
JUST A HORRIFIC DAY HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,  ATHIS
COMMUAS
THIS COMMUNITY IS COMING TO
GRIPS WITH THIS TERRIBLE
MASSACRE, WOLF.
>> SO RYAN LANZA, YOU KNOW THE
SPELLING OF HIS LAST NAME,
SUSAN?
>> RYAN.
IT IS RYAN.
I DON'T KNOW WHETHER YOU SAID
BRIAN, BUT RYAN LANZA WITH AN R,
EXACTLY IN HIS 20s.
WE'RE STILL TRYING TO FIND OUT
MORE INFORMATION, GET CONFIRMED
INFORMATION ABOUT WHAT
CONNECTION HE MAY HAVE IF ANY TO
THE SCHOOL, AND WE DO KNOW THAT
WOULD BE STANDARD OPERATING
PROCEDURE, THAT POLICE WOULD BE
ACTIVELY SEARCHING HIS HOME FOR
ANY CLUES AS TO WHAT MAY HAVE
ALLEGEDLY LED HIM TO THIS.
WE DO KNOW, ACCORDING TO ANOTHER
SOURCE, THAT AT LEAST TWO
WEAPONS WERE RECOVERED FROM HIS
BODY, WHICH WAS DISCOVERED IN A
CLASSROOM.
WE DO NOT KNOW WHETHER HE TOOK
HIS OWN LIFE OR WHETHER HE WAS
SHOT BY POLICE OR IN SOME OTHER
WAY.
THOSE TWO WEAPONS DESCRIBED TO
ME AS A GLOCK AND A SIX HAUR AND
WE DON'T KNOW THE CALIBER OF
WEAPONS, BUT WE HEARD MULTIPLE
SHOTS WERE FIRED.
EYEWITNESSES TALK ABOUT THAT AS
WELL.
AND THEY ARE STILL CONDUCTING
SEARCHES THROUGHOUT THE SCHOOL.
YOU HEARD AUTHORITIES SAY
THEY'RE SATISFIED THAT THERE ARE
NO OTHER VICTIMS INSIDE THAT
SCHOOL.
WE DO NOT KNOW THE NUMBERS OF
THOSE WOUNDED.
>> THEY SAY THE AREA IS NOW
SECURE.
THOUGH THE HORRIFIC SCENE
OBVIOUSLY NEEDS TO BE
INVESTIGATED THOROUGHLY.
JUST TO RECAP, CLOSER TO 30
CONFIRMED DEAD NOW, SUSAN, BASED
ON YOUR REPORTING.
18 TO 20 OF THEM CHILDREN.
WE DON'T KNOW HOW MANY
INDIVIDUALS, CHILDREN, ADULTS,
WERE INJURED.
WE DO KNOW THAT SEVERAL WERE
TAKEN TO NEARBY HOSPITALS,
ESPECIALLY IN DANBURY,
CONNECTICUT.
IS ALL THAT CORRECT, SUSAN?
>> Reporter: THAT'S CORRECT.
THAT'S CORRECT.
AND, OF COURSE, COUNSELING
SERVICES ARE ALREADY BEING MADE
AVAILABLE TO THE SURVIVING
CHILDREN AND ADULTS WHO HAVE
GONE THROUGH THIS TERRIBLE
EXPERIENCE AS THEY TRY TO WRAP
THEIR ARMS AROUND WHAT HAPPENED.
IMAGINE ALL THESE YOUNG CHILDREN
AS WELL AS ADULTS WHO HEARD
GUNFIRE, WHO WERE HURRIED OUT OF
THE SCHOOL, JUST AS SOON AS
POLICE SAID IT WAS SAFE FOR THEM
TO DO SO.
WHILE POLICE CONDUCTED A
THOROUGH SEARCH OF THAT SCHOOL.
THEY SAID THEY'RE SATISFIED THAT
THAT SCHOOL HAS BEEN CLEARED.
HOWEVER, THEY STILL NEED ALL THE
ADDITIONAL INFORMATION TO TRY TO
FIND OUT WHAT LED TO THE
SHOOTING, PRECISELY WHO THIS
SHOOTER IS AND WHAT MAY HAVE LED
TO THIS.
WOLF?
>> AND WHERE THIS SHOOTER GOT
THOSE TWO WEAPONS THAT WERE USED
IN THIS MASS MURDER AT THIS
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
SUSAN, STAND BY FOR A SECOND.
I WANT OUR VIEWERS TO LISTEN TO
WHAT A NURSE WHO RUSHED TO THE
SCENE TO HELP, WHAT SHE JUST
SAID.
>> I SEE YOU'VE BEEN CRYING.
>> YES.
>> IS IT BECAUSE OF WHAT YOU
SAW?
>> NO, THEY WOULDN'T EVEN LET US
IN THE BUILDING.
ALL I CAN SAY IS THAT ONE OF THE
COPS SAID, YOU KNOW, THE WORST
THING HE HAD EVER SEEN IN HIS
ENTIRE CAREER.
BUT IT WAS WHEN THEY TOLD THE
PARENTS, ALL THESE PARENTS WERE
WAITING FOR THEIR CHILDREN TO
COME OUT, THEY THOUGHT THAT THEY
WERE, YOU KNOW, STILL ALIVE.
AND THOSE 20 PARENTS THAT WERE
JUST TOLD THAT THEIR CHILDREN
ARE DEAD.
IT WAS AWFUL.
>> AND YOU WERE UNABLE TO DO
ANYTHING.
>> RIGHT.
WE KNEW AT ONE POINT THEY ASKED
THE AMBULANCES TO LEAVE, THAT
THEY DIDN'T NEED THEM, AND WE
KNEW THAT WASN'T A GOOD SIGN.
>> ALEXIS, YOU TOLD ME YOU WERE
SITTING IN CLASS THIS MORNING,
AND YOU SAW A LOT OF POLICE.
TELL ME HOW YOU FOUND OUT WHAT
WAS GOING ON.
>> WELL, WE FOUND, LIKE, THERE
WAS ALL THESE PEOPLE, AND WE
FOUND BECAUSE IT WAS RIGHT NEAR
THE WINDOW IN OUR CLASSROOM,
AND, LIKE, WE SAW, LIKE, POLICE
OFFICERS AND WE HEARD THEM ON
THE ROOF AND IN OUR BUILDING.
>> WAS EVERYBODY CRYING, SCARED,
WANTING THEIR PARENTS TO COME
GET THEM?
>> YEAH.
THEY WERE.
AND THEN SOME PEOPLE WERE EVEN,
LIKE, THEY KIND OF FELT THEY GOT
A STOMACH ACHE.
>> DID YOU HEAR ANY GUNSHOTS OR
ANYTHING LIKE THAT?
>> WELL, THE POLICE OFFICERS,
LIKE, THEY WERE -- THEY WERE
KIND OF, BECAUSE THEY WERE
POLICE OFFICERS, LIKE RIGHT OUT
THE DOOR TRYING TO FIND THE GUY.
>> WHAT A HORRIFIC SCENE INDEED,
JUST TO RECAP.
THE SHOOTER IN THIS CASE, THE
SUSPECTED GUNMAN IDENTIFIED NOW
AS RYAN LANZA.
IN HIS 20s.
THAT ACCORDING TO A LAW
ENFORCEMENT SOURCE WHO TOLD THAT
TO CNN, THE SHOOTER DIED AT THE
SCENE.
WE DON'T KNOW THE CIRCUMSTANCES
ON HOW HE DIED.
WE'RE WORKING THOSE DETAILS AS
WELL.
WE DO KNOW THAT THE PRESIDENT OF
THE UNITED STATES, PRESIDENT
OBAMA, HAS BEEN BRIEFED ON WHAT
IS GOING ON RIGHT NOW.
HE WANTS TO GET A FIRMER GRASP
ON WHAT IS GOING ON BEFORE HE
SPEAKS OUT PUBLICLY ACCORDING TO
OUR WHITE HOUSE CORRESPONDENT
BRIANNA KEILAR.
BUT HE WILL BE MAKING A
STATEMENT, JESSICA YELLIN, OUR
CHIEF WHITE HOUSE CORRESPONDENT,
DOES TELL US.
I THINK BASED ON OUR REPORTING
THE PRESIDENT WANTS TO WAIT
UNTIL THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT HAS ACTUALLY SPOKEN
UP ON THIS ISSUE, THE WHITE
HOUSE ANXIOUS TO GET
INFORMATION, THE PRESIDENT HAS
BEEN FULLY BRIEFED ON WHAT WE
KNOW RIGHT NOW.
AND, REMEMBER, A LOT OF TIMES IN
A SITUATION LIKE THIS, A
DEVELOPING SITUATION, SOME OF
THE INITIAL INFORMATION PROVES
TO BE INACCURATE, SO WE WANT TO
BE AS PRECISE AS WE POSSIBLY CAN
BE.
BASED ON OUR REPORTING FROM
SUSAN CANDIOTTI, THOUGH, WHO IS
NOW ON THE SCENE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, CLOSE TO 30 PEOPLE
ARE DEAD.
OF THEM, 18 TO 20 CHILDREN AT
THAT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI IS STILL WITH
US.
SUSAN, PARENTS WHO HAVE RUSHED
TO THAT SCHOOL, ESPECIALLY THOSE
PARENTS WHO ARE GETTING THE
AWFUL NEWS ABOUT THEIR KIDS, DO
YOU KNOW WHERE THEY ARE, HOW
THIS IS BEING HANDLED?
>> Reporter: WELL, I KNOW THAT
WHEN THE CHILDREN WERE FIRST LED
FROM THE SCHOOL, AND THIS WAS
AFTER POLICE SAID THEY HAD
SEARCHED EVERY CRACK AND
CREVICE, THEY SAID, OF THE
SCHOOL, TO MAKE SURE THAT IT WAS
SAFE TO EVACUATE THE CHILDREN,
THEY WERE LED, SOME OF THEM IN
LINES AND MAYBE YOU'VE SEEN
PICTURES OR VIDEOTAPE OF THIS,
WITH THE SMALL CHILDREN, WE'RE
TALKING ABOUT KINDERGARTEN TO
FOURTH GRADE, PLACING ONE CHILD
ON THE SHOULDERS IN FRONT OF
THEM AND BEING LED TO A NEARBY
FIREHOUSE WHICH IS USED AS A
STAGING AREA WHERE THEY HAD
ADULTS WHO HAD ALREADY BEGUN TO
TRY TO COMFORT THESE CHILDREN,
AND USE THAT SPACE AS SOME PLACE
FOR PARENTS TO GO TO BE
RECONNECTED, REUNITED WITH THEIR
CHILDREN.
WE KNOW THAT SOME OF THE PARENTS
TOLD US THEY FOUND OUT ABOUT
THIS, THE NEWS MEDIA, BUT OTHERS
QUICKLY GOT INFORMATION VIA
THEIR TEXT PHONE, OR E-MAILS,
SOMETHING THAT THEY COULD SIGN
UP FOR TO RECEIVE IMMEDIATE
MESSAGES FROM THE SCHOOL, WHICH
IS COMMON PLACE THESE DAYS.
WE ALSO KNOW, WOLF, THAT AFTER
THE SCHOOL WAS CLEARED, POLICE
AND INVESTIGATORS CONTINUE TO
LOOK THROUGH THE AREA, TO MAKE
SURE THAT, IN FACT, THERE MIGHT
NOT BE A SECOND SHOOTER
INVOLVED.
THEY HAD ISOLATED ONE CAR IN
PARTICULAR, BUT WERE CONTINUING
TO WALK DOWN THE STREET AND
SEARCH AND LOOK AT OTHER
VEHICLES, OTHER BUILDINGS IN
THAT AREA.
ALSO, ACCORDING TO A SOURCE, WE
KNOW THAT SOMEONE ELSE WAS BEING
QUESTIONED, WHO WAS NOT BEING
CALLED A SUSPECT AT THIS TIME,
BUT SOMEONE ELSE IS BEING
QUESTIONED IN CONNECTION WITH
THIS INVESTIGATION.
THAT'S ALL WE HAVE ON THAT FOR
NOW.
HOWEVER, THE STATE POLICE DO SAY
THAT THEY HAVE AN ACTIVE SEARCH,
WE PRESUME THEY MEAN A SEARCH
WARRANT BEING CONDUCTED AT THE
HOME OF THE DEAD SHOOTER.
WOLF?
>> AND THE DEAD SHOOTER CAME IN
NOT ONLY WITH TWO WEAPONS, BUT
ALSO WITH ARMOR, I TAKE IT,
RIGHT?
IS THAT THE INFORMATION YOU'RE
GETTING, THIS RYAN LANZA, IN HIS
20s, WHO IS DEAD, BUT HE CAME IN
WITH NOT ONLY WEAPONS, BUT WITH
ARMOR?
IS THAT RIGHT?
>> Reporter: WELL, THERE ARE
REPORTS TO THAT EXTENT.
I DON'T HAVE THAT CONFIRMED
INFORMATION, BUT SOME PEOPLE ARE
REPORTING THAT AT THIS TIME.
WE'RE CALLING THOSE UNCONFIRMED
REPORTS RIGHT NOW.
>> STAND BY.
I WANT TO BRING IN BRIANA KEE B
KEELER OUR WHITE HOUSE
CORRESPONDENT.
THE PRESIDENT WILL MAKE A
STATEMENT TO THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW?
WHAT IS GOING ON OVER THERE?
>> HE'S BEEN RECEIVING REGULAR
UPDATES FROM HIS HOMELAND
SECURITY TEAM, SPECIFICALLY THIS
MORNING.
HE WAS FIRST BRIEFED OF THE
SITUATION IN CONNECTICUT AT
10:30 A.M., HIS HOMELAND
SECURITY ADVISER JOHN BRENNAN
ALERTED HIM AS TO THE
DEVELOPMENTS.
AND HE SINCE HAS BEEN RECEIVING
REGULAR UPDATES ACCORDING TO THE
WHITE HOUSE SPOKESMAN JAY
CARNEY.
WE DO KNOW, WOLF, HE'S EXPECTED
TO ADDRESS THIS, TO ACTUALLY
COME OUT BEFORE THE CAMERAS,
PERHAPS, AND GIVE SOME SORT OF
STATEMENT TO SPEAK TO THIS.
HE'S BEEN IN TOUCH WITH THE
GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT.
HE'S BEEN IN TOUCH WITH HIS FBI
DIRECTOR.
THE WHITE HOUSE HAS BEEN WAITING
TO GET A FIRMER GRASP ON THE
FACTS.
AS YOU KNOW, IT IS A VERY FLUID
SITUATION AND THE PRESIDENT
CERTAINLY WANTS TO KNOW HE HAS A
FIRM GRASP ON THE FACTS OF THE
CASE, WHAT IS GOING ON BEFORE HE
ADDRESSES THE NATION, WOLF.
>> IT LOOKS LIKE THIS MAY BE THE
WORST MASS KILLING AT A SCHOOL
IN U.S. HISTORY, BASED ON THE
INFORMATION I'M GETTING OVER
HERE.
COLUMBINE HIGH SCHOOL,
LITTLETON, COLORADO, BACK IN
1999, DYLAN KLEBOLD AND ERIC
HARRIS KILLED 12 FELLOW STUDENTS
AND ONE TEACH BROTHER BEFORE
COMMITTING SUICIDE IN THE SCHOOL
LIBRARY.
IN THIS CASE, JOHN KING
REPORTING CLOSE TO 30, WE
BELIEVE, ARE NOW DEAD.
AND 18 TO 20 OF THEM CHILDREN,
IF THOSE NUMBERS HOLD UP.
THIS LOOKS LIKE IT COULD BE THE
WORST MASS KILLING IN AMERICAN
HISTORY, SOMETHING NO ONE
ANTICIPATED WOULD BE HAPPENING
AT ANY POINT, BUT LISTEN TO THE
WHITE HOUSE PRESS SECRETARY JAY
CARNEY SPEAK ABOUT THIS, JUST A
LITTLE WHILE AGO.
>> THE PRESIDENT WAS NOTIFIED BY
HIS HOMELAND SECURITY ADVISER,
JOHN BRENNAN, OF THE SHOOTING IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, AT A
SCHOOL.
THE PRESIDENT IS RECEIVING
REGULAR UPDATES AS MORE
INFORMATION BECOMES AVAILABLE
ABOUT THIS INCIDENT.
AND AS THE DAY PROCEEDS, IF WE
GET MORE INFORMATION AND AS WE
GET MORE INFORMATION, WE'LL
CERTAINLY PROVIDE IT TO YOU.
I DO NOT HAVE ANYTHING TO
CONFIRM FOR YOU AT THIS POINT.
THE FBI IS SUPPORTING STATE LAW
ENFORCEMENT, WHICH HAS THE LEAD
AS WELL AS LOCAL LAW ENFORCEMENT
AS THEY RESPOND TO AND BEGIN TO
INVESTIGATE THIS INCIDENT.
AND AS I SAID, THE PRESIDENT
WILL RECEIVE REGULAR UPDATES AS
THE DAY PROGRESSES.
>> JAY CARNEY, THE WHITE HOUSE
PRESS SECRETARY, THE PRESIDENT
GOING TO HAVE TO DEAL WITH THIS
MASS KILLING IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
OTHER PRESIDENTS HAVE DEALT WITH
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS ONE.
THIS PRESIDENT CERTAINLY IS
GETTING READY TO DEAL WITH IT IN
IN AN ADDRESS TO THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE.
GIVE US A PERSPECTIVE ON WHAT IS
GOING ON BEHIND THE SCENES OVER
THERE AT THE WHITE HOUSE.
>> Reporter: IT IS SOMETHING THE
PRESIDENT HAS ALREADY DEALT WITH
IN -- I DON'T WANT TO SAY IN A
SIMILAR SITUATION, WOLF, BECAUSE
OBVIOUSLY EVERY TRAGEDY IS
DIFFERENT, BUT FOLLOWING THE
SHOOTING OF CONGRESSWOMAN
GIFFORDS, AND FOLLOWING THE
TERRIBLE SHOOTING AT THE MOVIE
THEATER IN COLORADO, THESE WERE
POINTS IN TIME WHERE PRESIDENT
OBAMA, AS OTHER PRESIDENTS
BEFORE HIM, HAD TO STEP IN AND
GIVE A UNIFIED MESSAGE AND
CERTAINLY A VOICE OF SYMPATHY
AND UNDERSTANDING FOR THE PEOPLE
WHO ARE AFFECTED BY A SHOOTING
LIKE THIS.
YOU COVERED VIRGINIA TECH.
I WAS THERE AS WELL.
THAT WAS SOMETHING WHERE WE SAW
THEN GOVERNOR CAINE AND
PRESIDENT GEORGE BUSH COME IN AS
VOICES BECAUSE IN A TRAGEDY LIKE
THIS, OBVIOUSLY, THERE ARE A LOT
OF QUESTIONS THAT ARE RAISED.
THERE ARE A LOT OF CONCERNS THAT
ARE RAISED IN THAT SORT OF --
THAT'S ONE OF THE ROLES OF THE
PRESIDENT IN A SITUATION LIKE
THIS, TO TRY TO SPEAK TO THAT
AND BE A UNIFYING VOICE.
BEHIND THE SCENES, WE KNOW,
WOLF, PRESIDENT OBAMA IS BEING
REGULARLY UPDATED ON THIS.
YOU KNOW, PRIOR TO THIS MORNING,
OBVIOUSLY THE CONCERNS WERE VERY
MUCH SURROUNDING SOMETHING VERY
DIFFERENT, TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
A DEAL OR TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHERE TO GO WITH THE ISSUE OF
THE FISCAL CLIFF.
AT THIS POINT, OBVIOUSLY,
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S ATTENTIONS
HAVE BEEN CHANGED, UNEXPECTEDLY,
TO HOW TO DEAL WITH THIS
SHOOTING IN CONNECTICUT AND
EXACTLY GRASPING -- THIS IS
SOMETHING HIS TEAM AROUND HIM IS
WORKING ON, THE DETAILS OF THE
INVESTIGATION, OBVIOUSLY.
SOME OF THE INFORMATION WILL BE
SOMETHING THAT THE WHITE HOUSE,
THAT THE PRESIDENT AND HIS
ADVISERS ARE PRIVY TO BEFORE
MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC ARE, WOLF.
>> AND THE PRESIDENT WILL BE
MAKING A STATEMENT.
WE DON'T KNOW EXACTLY WHEN OR
WHERE.
SOME PLACE IN THE WHITE HOUSE
HE'LL BE SPEAKING OUT.
ARE THEY PREPARING FOR THAT
ALREADY?
WE KNOW HE WANTS TO -- HE WANTS
TO HEAR FROM THE GOVERNOR FIRST,
THE GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT.
>> Reporter: LET ME TELL YOU
THAT, BECAUSE I REPORTED THAT,
THAT HE WAS WAITING TO HEAR FROM
THE GOVERNOR.
I'M NOW TOLD BY THE SAME SENIOR
ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL THAT I
SPOKE WITH BEFORE THAT HE MAY
NOT BE WAITING FOR THE GOVERNOR
TO SPEAK FIRST BECAUSE HE'S HAD
THIS PHONE CONVERSATION WITH
GOVERNOR MALLOY.
IT IS ENTIRELY POSSIBLE THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA COMES OUT AND
MAKES A STATEMENT BEFORE THE
GOVERNOR.
I THINK THAT MAY BE AN
INDICATION THAT PERHAPS THE
TIMELINE COULD BE MOVED UP, BUT
BEYOND WHAT IT WAS BEFORE, BUT
AT THIS POINT, IT IS VERY FLUID.
IT DOESN'T APPEAR TO BE SET AND
IT IS CERTAINLY NOT PUBLIC AS TO
WHEN THE PRESIDENT WILL MAKE A
STATEMENT, WOLF.
>> WE'LL STAND BY, HAVE COVERAGE
OBVIOUSLY OF THAT.
AND WE HAVE BEEN TOLD BY THE
GOVERNORS AID, ONE OF THE
GOVERNOR'S AIDS THAT HE IS
MEETING WITH FAMILIES, TRYING TO
CONSOLE THEM.
HE'S ON THE SCENE.
AT SOME POINT THE GOVERNOR,
DANNEL MALLOY WILL BE SPEAKING
AS WELL.
DAVID ARIOSO IS ON THE SCENE.
FROM YOUR ADVANTAGE POINT,
DAVID, TELL US WHAT YOU'RE
SEEING.
>> I'M RIGHT OUTSIDE THE
FIREHOUSE BEING USED AS A
MAKESHIFT SHELTER FOR WHICH
FAMILY MEMBERS, INCLUDING
PARENTS AND CHILDREN, ARE HOLED
UP.
YOU DO SEE PARENTS WALKING BACK
AND FORTH ON A WOODED STRETCH
THAT LEADS UP TOWARD THE SCHOOL,
OFTENTIMES CLUTCHING THEIR
CHILDREN, CLUTCHING EACH OTHER,
TALKING ON CELL PHONES AND
ALMOST ALL THE WHILE THEY'RE
TEARY EYED.
MOST PEOPLE WON'T SPEAK WITH US,
WE DID GET A CHANCE TO SPEAK TO
ONE LITTLE GIRL, AN 8-YEAR-OLD,
THIRD GRADER, WHO WAS INSIDE THE
SCHOOL WHEN ALL THIS TRANSPIRED.
POLICE ESSENTIALLY BARGED IN,
THE TEACHERS BARGED IN AND
ORDERED THEM TO HIDE IN THE
CLASSROOM.
THEY WERE ALL CRYING AS POLICE
AND AUTHORITIES TRIED TO FIGURE
OUT WHAT THE SITUATION WAS, WHAT
THE CRISIS WAS.
AND ESSENTIALLY THEIR PARENTS
WERE INFORMED BY AN AUTOMATED
PHONE CALL THAT THERE HAD BEEN A
SHOOTING AT A SCHOOL.
THEY DIDN'T INDICATE WHICH
SCHOOL, AND SO MANY OF THE
PARENTS HERE IN THE REGION
FRANTICALLY FLOCKED TO THE
SCHOOLS WHERE THEY HAD CHILDREN
ATTENDING.
THIS PARTICULAR PARENT I SPOKE
TO WAS FRANTIC, ARRIVED HERE AT
THE SCHOOL AND FORTUNATELY FOUND
HER DAUGHTER UNHARMED.
SO WHEN WE MET UP WITH HER, SHE
WAS CLUTCHING HER, THROWING THIS
OVERSIZED COAT AROUND HER AS
THEY WALKED UP THE ROAD AND AWAY
FROM THE SCHOOL.
AND IT IS REALLY ONE OF THOSE
SCENES, WOLF, THAT YOU REALLY
JUST CAN'T PUT YOUR FINGER ON
AND ASK ENOUGH QUESTIONS AS TO
WHY ALL THIS TRANSPIRED.
THE COMMUNITY HERE IS STILL VERY
MUCH IN SHOCK.
THERE ARE QUESTIONS NOT ONLY OF
WHAT ACTUALLY TRANSPIRED IN
TERMS OF THE DETAILS, BUT WHY
SOMEONE WOULD DO THIS.
A LOT OF TEARS HERE IN THIS
TOWN, SORT OF THE SLEEPY NEW
ENGLAND TOWN, ABOUT AN HOUR
NORTH OF NEW YORK CITY.
>> ABOUT 60 MILES OR SO, NOT FAR
AWAY FROM NEW YORK CITY AS WELL,
MUCH CLOSER TO DANBURY,
CONNECTICUT.
DAVID, HOLD ON FOR A MOMENT.
MARY SNOW IS IN NEWTOWN AS WELL,
OUTSIDE THE SUSPECT'S HOME, WHAT
ARE YOU SEEING OVER THERE, MARY?
>> WE'RE BEING KEPT FAR BACK
FROM THE SUSPECT'S HOME.
THE POLICE HAVE CORDONED OFF
THIS AREA.
THERE ARE MULTIPLE LAW
ENFORCEMENT VEHICLES LINED UP
AND RESIDENTS, WOLF, ARE BEING
KEPT AWAY FROM THEIR HOMES AS
WELL AND LOOKING AT A CAR, A
LINE OF VEHICLES LINED UP OF
RESIDENTS WHO ARE TOLD THEY
CANNOT GO TO THEIR HOMES BECAUSE
POLICE TAPE HAS BEEN PUT UP.
AND THERE ARE MORE THAN A DOZEN
LAW ENFORCEMENT VEHICLES HERE.
>> THE SUSPECT, MARY, NOW
DECEASED, DIED AT THE SCENE, WE
DON'T KNOW THE CIRCUMSTANCES
SURROUNDING THAT, RYAN LANZA, IN
HIS 20s.
ARE YOU GETTING ANY INFORMATION
AT ALL IF HE HAD A DIRECT
CONNECTION TO THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, WHERE THIS
MASS KILLING TOOK PLACE?
>> NOT AS YET.
AND I HAVE TO TELL YOU, WOLF, WE
APPROACHED SOME OF THE RESIDENTS
HERE.
THEY'RE SO SHAKEN TO THE CORE AS
YOU CAN IMAGINE.
ONE WOMAN FILLING UP WITH TEARS
SAYING THERE ARE SO MANY SMALL
CHILDREN IN THIS AREA, THAT SHE
COULDN'T REALLY BRING HERSELF TO
TALK TO US WHEN I ASKED HER
ABOUT THE LANZAS AND THEIR
CONNECTION.
WE DON'T HAVE ANY INFORMATION
JUST YET FROM HERE ABOUT ANY
CONNECTION TO THE SCHOOL.
>> MARY, WE'RE GOING TO CHECK
BACK WITH YOU.
MARY SNOW IS NOT FAR AWAY FROM
THE SUSPECT'S HOME IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
RYAN LANZA IN HIS 20s, DIED AT
THE SCENE.
ONE OF OUR CNN EXECUTIVES,
MEREDITH ARTILY, HAS BEEN ON THE
SCENE AS WELL AND SHE SPOKE WITH
AN EYEWITNESS.
LISTEN TO THIS.
>> SHE CONVEYED TO ME THAT SHE
WAS IN A MEETING THIS MORNING,
SAID IT WAS AROUND 9:30, 9:35,
AND SHE -- THERE WERE ABOUT
SEVEN PEOPLE IN THE ROOM, AND IT
WAS A MEETING REGARDING ONE OF
HER KIDS, SHE HAS CHILDREN AT
THE SCHOOL.
AND SHE VOLUNTEERS AT THE SCHOOL
AS WELL.
AND SHE HEARD -- SHE DESCRIBED
IT AS A POP, POP, POP IN THE
HALL.
AND THEY ALL HEARD IT.
THERE WAS SEVEN PEOPLE IN THE
MEETING ROOM.
THEY HEARD THE SOUND IN THE
HALL.
AND THEY -- SHE SAID THREE
PEOPLE WENT OUT INTO THE HALL,
THE PRINCIPAL, THE VICE
PRINCIPAL AND THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST.
AND TO HEAR HER DESCRIBE IT, SHE
SAID THREE PEOPLE WENT OUT INTO
THE HALL, AND ONLY ONE -- ONLY
ONE PERSON CAME BACK, THE VICE
PRINCIPAL, SHE SAID, WHO WAS
SHOT IN THE LEG OR THE FOOT, WHO
CAME CRAWLING BACK.
AND SHE SAID THAT SHE COWERED
UNDER THE TABLE DURING THAT
MOMENT, AND CALLED 911.
AS DID THE OTHER PEOPLE IN THE
ROOM.
SHE SAID SHE NEVER SAW THE
SHOOTER, THAT SHE WAS, YOU KNOW
SHE WAS UNDER THE TABLE, THAT
THE SHOOTING HAPPENED IN THE
HALLWAY.
AND TO HEAR HER DESCRIBE IT, SHE
SAID THERE MUST HAVE BEEN 100
ROUNDS.
AND I ASKED HER TO CLARIFY THAT,
I SAID, REALLY, TRULY, 100
ROUNDS, SHE SAID AT LEAST.
>> WHEN THE VICE PRINCIPAL CAME
CRAWLING BACK, WHAT HAPPENED AT
THAT POINT?
WHAT DID SHE SAY?
HOW DID THE VICE PRINCIPAL
MANAGE TO MOVE OR ESCAPE?
DID SHE DESCRIBE WHAT WAS THE
SITUATION AS HE WAS CRAWLING
BACK?
>> SHE DESCRIBED -- SHE SAID
THAT -- SHE SAID THERE WAS
CONFUSION THERE WAS YELLING AND
UNDERSTANDABLY, SHE SAID THERE
WAS YELLING IN THE HALLWAY, AND
SHE COULDN'T -- SHE COULDN'T
TELL FOR A WHILE IF IT WAS THE
POLICE OR THE SHOOTER IT.
WHEN I TALKED TO HER, SHE WAS
STILL INSIDE THE SCHOOL, THE
SCHOOL WAS ON LOCKDOWN SHE
DIDN'T KNOW IF THE SHOOTER WAS
DEAD YET OR STILL THERE.
>> WHAT DID THE VICE PRINCIPAL
LOOK LIKE?
WHEN SHE SAW HIM RETURN?
>> I DIDN'T -- I DIDN'T HEAR HER
DESCRIBE THAT.
SHE SAID, YOU KNOW, SHE SAID,
LISTEN, THIS IS A NICE TOWN,
THIS IS A NICE SCHOOL, THESE ARE
THE KIND OF THINGS THAT DON'T
HAPPEN THERE.
SHE NOTED THIS WAS NOT SOME HIGH
POWERED MEETING.
IT WAS, YOU KNOW, ABOUT MY --
ABOUT ONE OF MY CHILDREN WHO WAS
IN SECOND GRADE THERE.
AND SHE -- SHE WAS TEARFUL,
SHE'S, YOU KNOW, JUST
UNDERSTANDABLY PANICKED, AND SHE
SAID THEY MARCHED, AT SOME
POINT, I DON'T HAVE THE LENGTH
OF TIME, BUT SHE SAID AT SOME
POINT AFTER THE SHOOTING THEY
MARCHED US OUT IN THE HALLWAY,
RIGHT PAST THE TWO BODIES,
LAYING IN THE HALLWAY IN A POOL
OF BLOOD.
>> WHEN SHE TALKED ABOUT THE TWO
BODIES, IS THAT OF THE PRINCIPAL
AND THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST WHEN
SHE SAID THOSE TWO HAD NOT
RETURNED?
ARE THOSE THE TWO INDIVIDUALS
THAT SHE --
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
>> AND DID SHE SAY OR DESCRIBE
IN ANY WAY WHAT THEIR CONDITIONS
LOOKED LIKE WHEN SHE PASSED IN
THE HALLWAY?
>> NO, SHE DID NOT.
SHE DID NOT.
SHE -- WE HAD A SHORT
CONVERSATION, SHE IS
UNDERSTANDABLY EMOTIONAL.
THOSE ARE PRETTY MUCH THE GIST
OF -- THAT'S THE GIST OF OUR
CONVERSATION.
>> THAT CONVERSATION, MEREDITH
ARTLEY, THE MANAGING EDITOR OF
CNN.COM HAD.
WE'RE STANDING BY, WE'RE NOW
TOLD ABOUT AN HOUR OR SO FROM
NOW THE GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT,
DANNEL MALLOY, WILL BE MAKING A
STATEMENT, AND ANSWERING
REPORTERS' QUESTIONS.
WE'LL, OF COURSE, HAVE LIVE
COVERAGE OF THAT.
WE'RE ALSO GETTING MORE
INFORMATION ON WHAT HAS
HAPPENED, JUST TO UPDATE OUR
VIEWERS WHO MAY JUST BE TUNING
IN NOW AT THE BOTTOM OF THE
HOUR.
CNN NOW HAS BEEN TOLD BY LAW
ENFORCEMENT AUTHORITIES CLOSE TO
30 PEOPLE HAVE BEEN KILLED,
KILLED IN THIS MASS SHOOTING
INCIDENT IN CONNECTICUT AT THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THAT'S NOT FAR AWAY FROM
DANBURY, 60 MILES OUTSIDE OF NEW
YORK CITY.
OF THOSE 30, NEARLY 30 KILLED,
WE'RE TOLD 18 TO 20 OF THEM ARE
CHILDREN.
WE DON'T KNOW HOW MANY PEOPLE
HAVE BEEN INJURED.
WE'RE GETTING MORE INFORMATION
COMING IN FROM EYEWITNESSES AND
LAW ENFORCEMENT AUTHORITIES, BUT
RIGHT NOW WANT TO BRING IN
RONALD STEVENS, THE EXECUTIVE
DIRECTOR OF THE NATIONAL SCHOOL
SAFETY CENTER, WHO DEALS WITH
SCHOOL SAFETY ALL OVER THE
COUNTRY.
PUTS OUT PROTOCOLS, WHAT SHOULD
BE DONE.
WHEN YOU HEARD ABOUT THIS,
RONALD, WHAT DID YOU THINK?
>> THIS WAS TRULY TRAGIC THAT
SOMEONE WOULD ATTACK THE MOST
INNOCENT OF ALL CHILDREN,
PARTICULARLY WITH THESE
YOUNGSTERS BEING IN GRADES K
THROUGH 4.
A LOT OF THE VIOLENCE WE DEAL
WITH IS WITH THOSE AT THE HIGH
SCHOOL LEVEL, BUT TRULY A TRAGIC
AND DIFFICULT SITUATION FOR
EVERYONE IN CONNECTICUT.
>> SO WHAT DO WE DO ABOUT THIS
KIND OF -- YOUR JOB IS TO MAKE
SURE OUR SCHOOLS, WHETHER LITTLE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS, LIKE THIS
ONE, OR MIDDLE SCHOOLS, OR HIGH
SCHOOLS, THEY ARE SAFE FOR
PARENTS TO DROP OFF THEIR KIDS,
NOT HAVE TO WORRY ABOUT THESE
KINDS OF INCIDENTS.
WHAT DO YOU DO IN THE AFTERMATH
OF THIS HORRIFIC MASS MURDER?
>> WELL, IN THE AFTERMATH WE
NEED TO GO BACK AND TAKE A LOOK
AT WHAT DID UNFOLD.
WHEN YOU HAVE SHOOTERS WHO ARE
COMMITTED TO COME ON TO A CAMPUS
WITH HIGH POWERED SEMIAUTOMATIC
WEAPONS, THERE IS NOT A WHOLE
LOT THAT CAN BE DONE WHEN THIS
STAFF IS UNARMED AND WHEN THEY
ATTACK CHILDREN WHO ARE SO
YOUNG.
AND OFTENTIMES OUR ELEMENTARY
SCHOOLS ARE THE LAST OF THE
SCHOOLS TO EVER GET AN ARMS
SCHOOL RESOURCE OFFICER OR
SOMEONE LIKE THAT.
THIS IS A TRAGIC REMINDER OF HOW
VULNERABLE OUR CHILDREN CONTINUE
TO BE.
AND, YOU KNOW, THERE ARE JUST
LIMITATIONS ON WHAT THE SCHOOL
CAN DO.
THEY NEED TO HAVE GOOD SAFE,
SCHOOL PLANS IN PLACE.
ADEQUATE SUPERVISION, BUT WHEN
YOU HAVE SOMEONE WHO IS DERANGED
AND COMES ON THE CAMPUS LIKE
THIS, IT IS TRULY TRAGIC.
>> THIS IS A SMALL SCHOOL, A
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADE, LESS THAN 600 STUDENTS
ATTEND THIS SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
RONALD, HOLD ON FOR A MOMENT.
JOHN KING IS GETTING MORE
INFORMATION FOR US.
WHAT ARE YOU LEARNING, JOHN?
>> Reporter: WOLF, I WANT TO
PASS ON SOME INFORMATION.
THIS IS FROM A SECOND FEDERAL
LAW ENFORCEMENT SOURCE I SPOKE
TO IN WASHINGTON, D.C., GETTING
INFORMATION FROM FBI OFFICIALS
ON THE SCENE, OTHER FEDERAL AND
STATE AUTHORITIES ON THE SCENE.
THIS SOURCE NOW SAYING THAT 27
IS THE NEW, BUT STILL
PRELIMINARY NUMBER.
THEY ARE WORKING OFF NOW.
THEY BELIEVE 27 KILLED IN THIS
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
THEY CALL THAT NUMBER NEW BUT
PRELIMINARY, BUT THERE COULD BE
ADDITIONAL INFORMATION.
IN A BREAKING NEWS TRAGEDY LIKE
THIS, OFTEN THE NUMBERS CHANGE
AS THE DAY GOES ON AND MORE N
INFORMATION BECOMES AVAILABLE.
OF THE 27 THIS SOURCE SAID AT
LEAST 18, AT LEAST 18 OF THE
DEAD ARE CHILDREN AT THE SCHOOL
TODAY.
THIS SOURCE GOING ON TO SAY THAT
INFORMATION FROM THE SCENE IS
THE SHOOTER YOU'VE BEEN TALKING
ABOUT WITH OTHER REPORTERS WAS
BORN IN 1988, BELIEVE HE'S 24
YEARS OLE.
THAT'S INFORMATION FROM THE
SCENE.
THEY BELIEVE THAT IS RELIABLE
INFORMATION.
AND THAT THE SHOOTER WHO IS DEAD
AT THE SCENE IS, QUOTE, NOT A
STRANGER TO THE SCHOOL, NOT A
STRANGER TO THE SCHOOL.
THIS OFFICIAL SAID.
HE ALSO SAID THE SHOOTINGS,
QUOTE, HAPPENED RELATIVELY
QUICKLY AND IN THE SAME
CONCENTRATED AREA OF THE SCHOOL.
HE WAS NOT RUNNING THE HALLS,
MEANING NOT RUNNING THE HALLS
FIRING THE WEAPON.
SO THE SOURCE, AGAIN, I WANT TO
REITERATE SAY HAPPENED
RELATIVELY QUICKLY AND IN THE
SAME CONCENTRATED AREA OF THE
SCHOOL, AND, AGAIN, THIS SOURCE
SAYING 27 IS THE NUMBER NOW
OPERATING ON.
YOU MENTIONED.
WE'LL HEAR FROM THE GOVERNOR
SHORTLY, HE'S ASKED STATE POLICE
AT THE SCENE AND OTHERS AT THE
SCENE NOT TO RELEASE THE FIRM
NUMBER UNTIL HE CAN SPEAK TO ALL
OF THE FAMILIES INVOLVED, BUT
WE'RE GETTING AT ROUGHLY
CONSISTENT IN THAT AREA, THIS
SOURCE SAYING 27 IS THE NUMBER
THEY BELIEVE.
A FEDERAL OFFICIAL, A SECOND
SOURCE I SPOKE TO EARLIER SAID
HE WAS HEARING 26 OR 27 AND
CERTAINLY SAID THEY ARE
CONVINCED FROM THE REPORTS
THEY'RE GETTING FROM THE SCENE
THAT THE NUMBER OF DEAD, WOLF,
CLOSER TO 30 THAN TO 20.
>> ANY WORD AT ALL ON INJURIES?
WE KNOW LOCAL HOSPITALS HAVE
RECEIVED INJURED STUDENTS AND
OTHERS.
>> Reporter: I WAS TOLD BY ONE
OF THE FIRST SOURCE EARLIER THAT
SEVERAL PEOPLE WERE WOUNDED AND
TAKEN TO LOCAL HOSPITALS BECAUSE
THEY WERE SO FOCUSED ON TRYING
TO GET THE NUMBER OF FATALITIES
AND TRYING TO DEAL WITH MAKING
SURE THAT THEY HAD DOUBLED,
TRIPLE CHECKED THAT SCHOOL, BOTH
FOR EVIDENCE AND TO MAKE SURE
THERE WERE NO OTHER BODIES, NO
OTHER PEOPLE HIDING, THAT IN MY
CONVERSATIONS WITH THE SOURCES,
THAT WAS THEIR URGENT CONCERN.
THE SOURCE I DID SPEAK TO
EARLIER, THIS IS A LITTLE MORE
THAN AN HOUR AGO, THE FIRST
SOURCE SAID THAT SEVERAL PEOPLE
WERE WOUNDED, DID NOT HAVE ANY
INFORMATION ON THE SEVERITY OF
THOSE INJURIES.
>> AWAITING WORD FROM THE
GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT, DANNEL
MALLOY, ALSO AWAITING WORD FROM
THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES, BOTH, WE'RE TOLD, WILL
BE MAKING STATEMENTS SOON.
WE'LL GET MORE INFORMATION FROM
BOTH THE PRESIDENT AND THE
GOVERNOR.
JOHN, STAND BY.
I KNOW YOU'RE WORKING YOUR
SOURCES, GETTING MORE
INFORMATION AS WELL.
BROOKE BALDWIN IS JOINING US
FROM THE CNN CENTER RIGHT NOW.
BROOKE, WHAT A HORRIFIC,
HORRIFIC MOMENT.
AT THE BEGINNING, I'M SURE LIKE
YOU, WHEN WE FIRST HEARD WORD OF
WHAT WAS GOING ON, WE THOUGHT,
YOU KNOW, ANOTHER INCIDENT, BUT
THEN THE HORRIFIC NUMBERS START
COMING IN AND YOU THINK OF THESE
LITTLE KIDS, KINDERGARTEN, FIRST
GRADE, SECOND GRADE, THIRD
GRADE, FOURTH GRADE IN A SMALL
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL LIKE THIS, AND
YOU SAY, HOW COULD THIS HAPPEN?
>> EXACTLY.
MY HEART IS HEAVY TODAY AND I
THINK MANY PEOPLE AROUND CNN,
AROUND THE NATION, AROUND THE
WORLD, ARE FEELING FOR THESE
PARENTS, THE PARENTS, OF COURSE,
OF THE SURVIVORS, BUT I'M
THINKING PARTICULARLY OF THESE
PARENTS WHO ARE SITTING IN THIS
FIREHOUSE, NEAR THIS SCHOOL,
WONDERING IF ONE OF THEIR
CHILDREN IS ONE OF THOSE WHO IS
NO LONGER WITH US.
AS WE CONTINUE TO WATCH THESE
PICTURES AND PRAY AND THINK
ABOUT THIS COMMUNITY, THIS
SLEEPY NEW ENGLAND COMMUNITY
HERE IN CONNECTICUT, I WANT TO
BRING IN VICTOR BLACKWELL, WHO
HAS BEEN SORT OF COMBING THROUGH
SOME OF THE DAY, AS THIS HAS
BEEN A VERY FLUID STORY.
WE HAVE BEEN HEARING FROM LITTLE
ONES, ADULTS, PARENTS, POLICE,
IT IS HORRIFIC.
>> AND IT IS A NATIONAL TRAGEDY.
BUT AS YOU LOOK AT THE CHILDREN,
AND THEIR PARENTS, YOU REALIZE
THIS IS ALSO A VERY PERSONAL
TRAGEDY.
A SMALL TOWN, A RELATIVELY SMALL
SCHOOL, AND THESE CHILDREN WERE
JUST GOING TO SCHOOL ON A NORMAL
DAY.
THEIR PARENTS GOT A ROBOCALL, AN
AUTOMATED CALL THERE HAD BEEN A
SHOOTING.
>> AT A SCHOOL.
AND THEN YOU IMAGINE THE
FEELINGS, THE RUSH TO THE
SCHOOL.
SO WE PUT TOGETHER FROM THESE
PARENTS, FROM THE CHILDREN, FROM
LAW ENFORCEMENT THIS HORRIFIC
MORNING IN NEWTOWN.
>> WHEN I WAS GETTING IN MY CAR,
I HEARD SIRENS GOING OFF
CONTINUOUSLY, CAR AFTER CAR
AFTER CAR, SOME OF THEM WERE
FLYING UP PAST MY HOUSE AND
COMING BACK AROUND AGAIN AND
GOING TO THE SCHOOL.
THIS HOUSE IS THREE HOUSES AWAY
FROM THE SCHOOL.
>> JUST AFTER 9:30 THIS MORNING
NEWTOWN POLICE RECEIVED A 911
CALL FOR AN EMERGENCY AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
NEWTOWN PD UPON OBTAINING
INFORMATION AS TO THE STATUS OF
THE SITUATION CONTACTED THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE AND
REQUESTED ASSISTANCE FROM STATE
POLICE AND SURROUNDING LOCAL
POLICE DEPARTMENTS.
>> WE SAW A POLICE OFFICER AND
WE HEARD THEM ON THE ROOF AND IN
OUR BUILDING.
>> DID YOU HEAR ANY GUNSHOTS OR
ANYTHING LIKE THAT?
>> WELL, POLICE OFFICERS, LIKE,
THEY WERE KIND OF, BECAUSE
THEY'RE POLICE OFFICERS, LIKE,
RIGHT OUT THE DOOR, LIKE TRYING
TO FIND THE GUY.
>> IT WAS SHOCKING.
I GOT THE CALL AT WORK THIS
MORNING AND I CAN'T BELIEVE A
SMALL TOWN LIKE THIS WOULD EVER
HAVE ANYTHING LIKE THIS HAPPEN.
AND TO BE IN AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, IT'S UNHEARD OF.
>> DOESN'T EVEN SEEM REAL.
IT JUST DOES NOT SEEM LIKE IT IS
EVEN POSSIBLE.
IT IS LIKE YOU READ IT IN THE
PAPER, SEE IT IN THE NEWS AND
YOU THINK, MY GOD, THAT POOR
FAMILY AND THEN YOU HAVE
SOMETHING HAPPEN SO CLOSE TO
HOME, IT'S, LIKE, I THINK I'M
STILL IN SHOCK.
>> I CAN TELL YOU THAT FIRST OF
ALL, OBVIOUSLY, OUR HEARTS AND
PRAYERS GO OUT TO THE VICTIMS OF
THIS TERRIBLE INCIDENT.
VERY TRAGIC.
OUR POLICE ARE CURRENTLY WORKING
CLOSELY WITH THE NEWTOWN POLICE
DEPARTMENT, WE HAVE MUTUAL AID
AGREEMENTS IN PLACE.
ALONG WITH THE STATE POLICE THAT
HAVE TAKEN A LEAD IN THIS
INVESTIGATION.
>> THE SCENE IS SECURE.
THE STATE POLICE MAJOR CRIMES
SQUAD AND NEWTOWN POLICE
DEPARTMENT, DANBURY STATE
ATTORNEY AND MANY AGENCIES ARE
WORKING TOGETHER TO ANSWER ALL
THE QUESTIONS SURROUNDING
EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED.
>> WAS EVERYBODY CRYING, SCARED,
WANTING THEIR PARENTS TO COME
GET THEM?
>> YEAH.
THEY WERE.
AND THEN SOME PEOPLE WERE EVEN,
LIKE, THEY KIND OF FELT THEY GOT
A STOMACH ACHE.
>> A STOMACH ACHE.
THAT JUST PUTS INTO CONTEXT,
WE'RE NOT TALKING AURORA.
THIS IS NOT FT. HOOD.
THIS IS NOT VIRGINIA TECH.
THIS IS K THROUGH 4, 5 THROUGH
9, MAYBE, AND YOU IMAGINE THAT
WITHOUT BEING MAUDLIN THAT
THOUGH THAT MOTHER OF ALEXIS,
SHE SAID HER HEART WAS IN A
MILLION PIECES, WHEN SHE HEARD
ABOUT THE SHOOTING, AND EVEN UP
TO THIS MOMENT OF ALL THIS
HAPPENING, SHE DOESN'T -- SHE
SAID IT DOESN'T SEEM REAL THERE
ARE STILL ALL THE PARENTS WHO
WILL GO HOME TODAY, AND
POSSIBLY, BECAUSE IT IS THE
HOLIDAY SEASON, ALREADY HAVE THE
HOUSE DECORATED FOR THE
HOLIDAYS.
>> THE GIFTS FOR THE KIDS.
>> THE GIFTS FOR THE KIDS NOT
COMING HOME.
IF THAT NUMBER HOLDS, 27 FROM
JOHN KING'S SOURCES, THAT WOULD
MAKE THIS THE SECOND DEADLIEST
MASS SHOOTING AND WOULD HAVE
BEEN THE SECOND DEADLIEST JUST
WITH THE 18 CHILDREN WHO WERE
KILLED TODAY.
>> IT IS HORRENDOUS.
I WAS -- I COVERED THE -- A
COUPLE OF ITTY-BITTY KIDS KILLED
IN THE AMISH SHOOTING, BUT THERE
IS NO COMPARISON.
THERE IS ABSOLUTELY NO
COMPARISON AS YOU POINT OUT,
WE'RE TALKING KIDS AS YOUNG AS
KINDERGARTNERS.
WOLF BLITZER, YOU HAVE A
DAUGHTER, I CAN'T BEGIN TO
IMAGINE.
MY HEART IS BLEEDING FOR THESE
FAMILIES RIGHT NOW.
>> SO SAD.
EVERYONE AROUND THE COUNTRY,
DARE I SAY AROUND THE WORLD, OUR
HEARTS ARE SO FILLED WITH
SADNESS RIGHT NOW.
AND IT IS ONLY GOING TO GET
WORSE AS WE GET MORE DETAILS AND
JUST IMAGINE, BROOKE, ONCE WE
START SEEING THE PICTURES OF
THESE DEAD LITTLE KIDS, IT IS
GOING TO BE AN AWFUL, AWFUL
SCENE FOR PEOPLE IN CONNECTICUT
ALL OVER THE WORLD, THAT WE WILL
ALL HAVE TO ENDURE AND LEARN
SOME PAINFUL LESSONS FROM WHAT
HAS JUST HAPPENED.
WE JUST GOT THIS COMMENT FROM A
YOUNG KID WHO WAS THERE ON THE
SCENE, WITNESSED WHAT WAS GOING
ON, AND SAID THIS.
>> THERE WAS, LIKE, POLICE
OFFICERS, LIKE, DOWN ON THE ROOF
AND THERE WAS ALSO IN THE
HALLWAYS.
>> WHAT WERE THEY KELLING YOU
GUYS?
>> THEY DIDN'T REALLY TELL US
ANYTHING.
JUST KEEP IN THE CLASSROOM.
>> THEY REMOVED YOU.
>> THEY MOVED THEM TO THE
FIREHOUSE.
THAT'S WHERE ALL THE PARENTS AND
EVERYBODY CAME.
>> WERE ALL THE KIDS BRAVE LIKE
YOU WERE?
>> SOME OF THEM WERE, LIKE, A
LITTLE SCARED.
BUT WE HAD TO GO THROUGH IT.
>> HOW DID YOU KNOW THEY WERE
SCARED?
>> EVERYBODY WAS, LIKE, CRYING
AND STUFF.
>> RONALD STEVENS IS WITH US,
THE EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF THE
NATIONAL SCHOOL SAFETY CENTER.
RONALD, WE KNOW THERE ARE SOME
SCHOOLS IN URBAN AREAS, BUT
ELSEWHERE, THAT HAVE METAL
DETECTORS AT THE DOORWAYS.
ARE WE GOING TO BE SEEING MORE
OF THIS NOW?
SHOULD WE SEE MORE OF THIS NOW?
>> IT'S POSSIBLE WE MIGHT SEE
MORE.
BUT EVEN WITH METAL DETECTORS,
THINGS HAPPEN SO QUICKLY, YOU
CAN THINK OF THE SITUATION AT
RED LAKE, MINNESOTA, WHERE THEY
HAD OFFICERS AND METAL DETECTORS
AT THE DOOR AND YET THE SHOOTER
STILL CAME IN.
IT IS ONE OF THOSE TRAGEDIES
THAT IS JUST SIMPLY
UNFATHOMABLE, AND I DON'T KNOW
OF ANY SCHOOL IN AMERICA THAT
WOULD BE PREPARED TO HANDLE AN
ASSAULT-LIKE INCIDENT THAT WE
HAVE BEEN HEARING ABOUT THIS
MORNING.
>> SO DOES THAT MEAN WE JUST
THROW UP OUR HANDS AND SAY THERE
IS NOTHING WE CAN DO?
>> I DON'T THINK IT MEANS THAT.
WHEN WE START LOOKING INTO THIS
MATTER AND DOING THE
INVESTIGATION, I THINK WE'RE
GOING TO FIND, I WILL PREDICT
WE'LL FIND THAT THERE WERE A
NUMBER OF WARNING SIGNS, IN
ADVANCE, MOST OF THE SHOOTINGS
LIKE THIS REFLECT THAT THERE
GENERALLY ARE MORE THAN ONE --
IS MORE THAN ONE PERSON
INVOLVED, AND THAT THERE WERE
SOME SIGNALS PERHAPS ALONG THE
WAY, BUT ONCE AGAIN, WE HAVE
SUCH INCREDIBLE FREEDOM IN THIS
COUNTRY, AND YET THAT COMES WITH
ENORMOUS RESPONSIBILITY AND TO
EVEN FATHOM THIS KIND OF TRAGEDY
VISITED UPON YOUNG CHILDREN OF
THIS NATURE IS STUNNING.
>> IT LOOKS LIKE NOW BASED ON
THE LATEST INFORMATION WE'RE
GETTING, JOHN KING REPORTING 27
DEAD, 18 OR SO OF THEM CHILDREN
IN THIS MASS SHOOTING IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE JUST GOT THIS REACTION IN
FROM A FATHER AND A SON WHO WERE
ON THE SCENE, THE FATHER
OBVIOUSLY WAS RUSHING THERE AND
PANICKED.
WATCH THIS.
WE DON'T HAVE IT YET.
BUT WE'RE GOING TO GET IT READY
FOR OUR VIEWERS.
MORE REACTION COMING IN, RONALD
STEVENS STILL WITH US, THE
EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF THE
NATIONAL SCHOOL SAFETY CENTER.
RONALD, IS THERE ANY ADVICE YOU
WANT TO GIVE TO PARENTS WHO ARE
WATCHING RIGHT NOW?
BECAUSE KIDS ARE IN SCHOOL ALL
OVER THE COUNTRY.
>> WELL, I WOULD JUST ENCOURAGE
PARENTS TO TELL THEIR CHILDREN
THAT THEY LOVE THEM, SPEND SOME
TIME WITH THEM, TRY TO OFFER
SOME FORM OF COMFORT, AND JUST
REALIZE HOW PRECIOUS THEY ARE.
I KNOW FROM MY OWN PERSPECTIVE
THIS MORNING I SAW THREE OF MY
GRANDCHILDREN BETWEEN THE SAME
AGES, 5 TO 9 OR 10, IN SCHOOL GO
AWAY.
IT IS A PARENT'S AND
ADMINISTRATOR'S WORST NIGHTMARE.
THE ADMINISTRATORS SAY THEY
NEVER THOUGHT IT WOULD HAPPEN
HERE, WHO EXPERIENCED THIS.
AND PARENTS JUST DON'T THINK IT
COULD HAPPEN IN THEIR
COMMUNITIES.
BUT THIS IS A VIVID REMINDER OF
WHERE OUR SOCIETY IS TODAY.
>> WE'RE NOW TOLD THE PRESIDENT
WILL BE IN THE WHITE HOUSE IN
THE WEST WING, HE'LL GO INTO THE
PRESS BRIEFING ROOM AT 3:15,
LESS THAN A HALF AN HOUR FROM
NOW.
3:15 P.M. EASTERN AND DELIVER A
STATEMENT ON THIS MASS KILLING
IN CONNECTICUT.
LISTEN TO THIS CLIP.
WE JUST GOT IT IN, A FATHER AND
SON AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> IT WAS TERRIFYING.
I'M STILL TERRIFIED.
I THINK I'M IN SHOCK ABOUT IT
ALL.
I STILL DON'T KNOW EVERYTHING
THAT HAPPENED.
I KNOW THERE WERE SOME PEOPLE
MISSING, THEY HAVE BEEN TAKEN TO
THE HOSPITAL.
I DON'T KNOW IF EVERYONE HAS
BEEN ACCOUNTED FOR.
IT IS TERRIFYING.
YOU KNOW, THE -- YOU RUSH OVER
HERE, AND YOU CAN'T GET TO WHERE
YOU NEED TO GO AND YOU HAVE TO
PARK DOWN HERE AND WALK.
I'M GLAD MY SON IS OKAY.
HE SEEMS TO BE HANDLING IT
ACTUALLY PRETTY GOOD RIGHT NOW.
I KNOW MY SON'S TEACHERS HAVE
BEEN OKAY AS WELL.
BUT I'VE HEARD OTHER TEACHERS
ARE NOT OKAY.
>> ONCE AGAIN, THE PRELIMINARY
REPORTS COMING IN RIGHT NOW, 27
DEAD, THAT NUMBER POTENTIALLY
COULD CHANGE.
18 TO 20, WE'RE TOLD, CHILDREN.
OTHERS, TEACHERS AND OTHERS AT
THE SMALL SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES WILL BE SPEAKING ON THIS
ISSUE AT 3:15 P.M. EASTERN FROM
THE WHITE HOUSE PRESS BRIEFING
ROOM.
WE'LL HAVE LIVE COVERAGE OF
THAT.
WE'RE ALSO AWAITING REMARKS FROM
THE GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT,
DANNEL MALLOY.
MUCH MORE COMING UP.
WE'RE FOLLOWING THE BREAKING
NEWS, A HORRIFIC, HORRIFIC
STORY, ONE OF THE LARGEST MASS
KILLINGS IN A SCHOOL IN THE
UNITED STATES, IN U.S. HISTORY,
THE STORY IS UNFOLDING RIGHT
NOW.
IF YOU THINK RUNNING
A RESTAURANT IS HARD,
TRY RUNNING FOUR.
FORTUNATELY WE'VE GOT INK.
IT GIVES US 5X THE REWARDS
ON OUR INTERNET, PHONE
CHARGES AND CABLE,
PLUS AT OFFICE SUPPLY STORES.
REWARDS WE PUT RIGHT
BACK INTO OUR BUSINESS.
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
WE'VE EVER WANTED TO DO
AND INK HELPS US DO IT.
MAKE YOUR MARK
WITH INK FROM CHASE.
>>> YOU ARE LOOKING AT IMAGES
THAT WE ARE NOW MULTIPLE HOURS
INTO THIS HORRIFIC, HORRIFIC
CRIME THAT HAS HAPPENED IN THIS
SMALL SLEEPY NEW ENGLAND TOWN OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
AT THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, THE
CALL CAME IN TO 911 AROUND 9:30
THIS MORNING, A GUNMAN WALKED
INTO THIS SCHOOL.
THE LATEST NUMBER WE HAVE, AND,
AGAIN, THESE ARE LOOSE NUMBERS,
THESE ARE PRELIMINARY NUMBERS,
BECAUSE LET ME STRESS THIS,
POLICE, LAW ENFORCEMENT, THEY
WANT TO GET THE INFORMATION TO
THE VICTIMS' FAMILIES FIRST, THE
NUMBERS COULD CHANGE.
WE'RE HEARING CLOSER TO 30 SK  L
KILLED AT THE SCHOOL.
AS FAR AS CHILDREN, LITTLE
CHILDREN, KINDERGARTEN THROUGH
FOURTH GRADE, SOMEWHERE BETWEEN
18 AND 20 CHILDREN.
THERE IS A FIREHOUSE, A
MAKESHIFT SHELTER FOR A LOT OF
THESE FAMILIES WHO SOME OF WHOM
HAVE THEIR CHILDREN, SOME OF
WHOM DO NOT.
WE WERE HEARING FROM JOHN KING,
FROM SOME OF HIS FEDERAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT SOURCES, THAT THE
SHOOTER, THIS -- IN HIS 20s,
RYAN LANZA, LET ME QUOTE THIS
FEDERAL LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICER,
SAYING RYAN LANZA NOT A STRANGER
TO THE SCHOOL, SAYING THAT THE
SHOOTINGS, QUOTE, HAPPENED
RELATIVELY QUICKLY AND IN THE
SAME CONCENTRATED AREA OF THE
SCHOOL.
HE WAS NOT RUNNING IN THE HALLS.
WE'RE GETTING NEW INFORMATION.
WE ALSO KNOW THAT THE PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED STATES HAS SPOKEN
WITH THE HEAD OF THE FBI.
HE HAS SPOKEN WITH THE GOVERNOR
OF CONNECTICUT.
HE MAY BE SPEAKING SHORTLY.
WANT TO TAKE YOU TO OUR CHIEF
WHITE HOUSE CORRESPONDENT
JESSICA YELLIN STANDING BY.
JESSICA, DO WE HAVE ANY IDEA IF
AND WHEN THE PRESIDENT WILL
SPEAK?
>> HI, BROOKE, YES.
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS GOING TO
SPEAK AT 3:15 P.M. EASTERN TIME.
THAT'S ABOUT 25 MINUTES FROM
NOW.
HE WILL COME TO THE PRESS
BRIEFING ROOM IN THE WHITE HOUSE
AND ADDRESS CAMERAS.
AND, YOU KNOW, THIS IS ONE OF
THE TIMES WHEN THE PRESIDENT IS
REALLY ABLE TO REALLY TOUCH A
CHORD.
YOU KNOW HE SPOKE VERY MOVINGLY
AFTER THE SHOOTINGS AROUND GABBY
GIFFORDS, THE ATTACK ON GABBY
GIFFORDS AND SO MANY PEOPLE ON
HER STAFF, WHEN HE SAID AT THAT
TIME, REMEMBER, IT IS PART OF
OUR NATURE TO DEMAND AN
EXPLANATI
EXPLANATION.
HE SAID AT THAT TIME, BAD THINGS
HAPPEN.
WE HAVE TO GUARD AGAINST SIMPLE
EXPLANATIONS IN THE AFTERMATH.
ALREADY TODAY, THE WHITE HOUSE
PRESS SECRETARY JAY CARNEY MADE
CLEAR THAT THIS IS NOT A TIME TO
TALK ABOUT POLITICAL AND POLICY
RESPONSES, BUT THINK ABOUT THE
FAMILIES AND HOW THEY ARE
REACTING, HOW THEY FEEL IN THE
AFTERMATH AND I EXPECT THAT'S
WHAT THE PRESIDENT WILL ADDRESS,
BOTH THE FEDERAL RESPONSE,
FEDERAL HELP, THE LAW
ENFORCEMENT, AND HOW THE NATION
WILL COME TOGETHER TO HELP THOSE
FAMILIES HEAL.
BROOKE?
>> JESSICA YELLIN, WE'LL WAIT
AND WATCH FOR THE PRESIDENT TO
SPEAK THERE FROM THE WHITE HOUSE
BRIEFING ROOM IN JUST ABOUT 25
MINUTES FROM NOW.
AND, WOLF BLITZER, BACK TO YOU,
BUT SOMETHING ELSE THAT JAY
CARNEY SAID EARLIER TODAY,
VIS-A-VIS THE PRESIDENT, THE
PRESIDENT HAS TWO YOUNG
DAUGHTERS, HE'S SYMPATHETIC TO
THESE PARENTS WHO, I'M SURE, ARE
JUST ABSOLUTELY REELING RIGHT
NOW.
>> YEAH.
HE SAYS THOSE TWO YOUNG
DAUGHTERS OF HIS, SASHA AND
MALIA, TO SCHOOL EVERY DAY LIKE
MILLIONS OF OTHER PARENTS DO
EVERY DAY, THEY DON'T EXPECT
WHAT HAS HAPPENED IN CONNECTICUT
TO UNFOLD.
IT IS A SHOCKING, SHOCKING STORY
THAT WE'RE WATCHING.
ONCE AGAIN, 3:15, 20 MINUTES OR
SO FROM NOW, 3:15 P.M. EASTERN,
THE PRESIDENT WILL BE IN THE
BRIEFING ROOM, MAKING A
STATEMENT TO THE NATION.
JOINING US NOW ON THE PHONE IS
RABBI PRAVER, A RABBI IN THE
AREA IN CONNECTICUT.
YOU'RE AT THE FIREHOUSE WHERE
PARENTS HAVE BEEN BROUGHT.
IS THAT RIGHT?
TELL US WHAT IS GOING ON THERE.
>> OKAY, WE'RE ALL GATHERED HERE
AT THE FIREHOUSE.
FIRST, WE WERE SPEAKING WITH THE
TEACHERS TO TAFIND OUT THE
STUDENTS WHO WERE ABSENT, NOT
ABSENT, AND THERE IS ANOTHER
ROOM WHERE THERE ARE PARENTS
WHOSE CHILDREN WERE TAKEN TO THE
HOSPITAL AFTER THE SHOOTING.
AND THEY'RE WAITING FOR THE
GOVERNOR TO RETURN TO PROVIDE
FURTHER INFORMATION ABOUT THEIR
CONDITION.
>> HAS THE GOVERNOR BEEN INSIDE
THAT FIREHOUSE WITH YOU,
SPEAKING TO PARENTS?
>> YES.
THE GOVERNOR WAS WITH US AND IS
COMING BACK AT 3:00.
>> THESE ARE PARENTS WHO MAY
HAVE LOST THEIR CHILDREN, WHO
MAY HAVE BEEN KILLED IN THIS
INCIDENT.
IS THAT WHAT YOU'RE --
>> YES, THAT'S WHAT I'M SAYING.
THEIR CHILDREN WERE TAKEN TO A
HOSPITAL, AND THERE IS A CERTAIN
AMOUNT OF CHILDREN TAKEN TO THE
HOSPITALS AND A CERTAIN AMOUNT
ALREADY, I THINK, MIGHT, WELL, I
DON'T THINK THEY KNOW
CONCLUSIVELY, BUT MANY OF THEM
SUSPECT, YOU KNOW, THAT THEIR
CHILDREN WERE VICTIMS, BUT WE'RE
JUST HOLDING OUT HOPE THAT THE
INJURED WILL, YOU KNOW, BE OKAY.
>> RABBI PRAVER, STAND BY FOR A
MOMENT.
MARY SNOW IS OUTSIDE THE
SUSPECT'S HOME, WE'RE TOLD, RYAN
LANZA.
MARY, TELL US WHAT YOU'RE
LEARNING.
>> WELL, WOLF, IT IS AN ACTIVE
CRIME SCENE AND THERE IS MORE
THAN A DOZEN LAW ENFORCEMENT
VEHICLES HERE.
WE'RE BEING KEPT BACK FROM THE
HOME.
IT IS CORDONED OFF.
WE DID SEE AN AMBULANCE LEAVE
THIS SCENE ABOUT 15 MINUTES AGO.
AND NEIGHBORS HAVE BEEN TOLD
TO -- THAT THEY CAN'T GO BACK
INTO THEIR HOMES.
ONE NEIGHBOR I SPOKE WITH SAID
THAT AROUND 11:00, POLICE CAME
AND TOLD HER TO EVACUATE RIGHT
AWAY.
SHE SAID SHE WAS BACK AN HOUR
LATER, WHERE POLICE ESCORTED HER
TO HER HOME, BUT SHE WAS TOLD
AGAIN TO LEAVE AND THERE IS NO
INDICATION OF WHEN THESE
RESIDENTS ARE GOING TO BE
ALLOWED BACK INTO THEIR HOME, IN
TERMS OF WHAT PEOPLE ARE SAYING
ABOUT THE LANZAS, I ONLY FOUND
ONE NEIGHBOR SO FAR WHO KNOWS OF
THE FAMILY.
SHE DID NOT WANT TO BE NAMED BUT
THE ONLY THING SHE WOULD TELL ME
IS THAT THERE WERE TWO BROTHERS,
AND SHE DESCRIBED THEM AS
TROUBLED.
BUT DIDN'T WANT TO GO ANY
FURTHER THAN THAT.
BUT THAT IS THE SCENE.
AND IT IS A BEAUTIFUL NEW
ENGLAND TOWN, VERY QUIET ROAD.
THE HOUSES ARE SET APART FROM
ONE ANOTHER.
AND RIGHT NOW THERE IS YELLOW
POLICE TAPE, BUT IT IS BLOCKING
ANYONE FROM GOING THROUGH.
AND THE LAW ENFORCEMENT VEHICLES
AND POLICE ARE STANDING GUARD
PREVENTING ANYBODY FROM GETTING
ANY FURTHER TO THE HOUSE.
>> NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, IS A
POPULATION OF UNDER 2,000
PEOPLE.
IT IS LOCATED IN FAIRFIELD
COUNTY, 45 MILES SOUTHWEST OF
HARTFORD, ABOUT 80 MILES
NORTHEAST OF NEW YORK CITY.
MARY, WE'LL GET BACK TO YOU.
THE SUSPECT -- THE SUSPECTED
GUNMAN, RYAN LANZA, IN HIS 20s,
HE DIED AT THE SCENE.
WE DON'T KNOW THE CIRCUMSTANCES.
WE'LL BE GETTING MORE
INFORMATION ON THAT.
JOINING US NOW, STEVE HARDY,
FORMER POLICE DETECTIVE, WHO
WORKED, UNFORTUNATELY, THESE
KINDS OF HOMICIDES OVER THE
YEARS.
WALK US THROUGH WHAT POLICE ARE
GOING THROUGH RIGHT NOW, STEVE.
>> WELL, FIRST OF ALL, WOLF,
THEY CERTAINLY ALREADY HAVE
TENDED TO THE WOUNDED, GET THE
INJURED OUT OF THERE, SECURE
THAT AREA, LOCATE AS MANY
WITNESSES AS POSSIBLE.
THAT SCHOOL IS GOING TO BE
CLOSED DOWN FOR PROBABLY A
LENGTHY PERIOD OF TIME, WHILE
THEY CONDUCT THEIR
INVESTIGATION.
THEY'RE GOING TO PUT THE PIECES
TOGETHER, IN CHRONOLOGICAL
ORDER, SEE HOW THIS HAPPENED,
WAS HE KILLED IN SELF-INFLICTED
GUNSHOT OR DID THE TEACHERS AND
THE PRINCIPAL FIGHT BACK,
DISARMING AND POSSIBLY KILLING
HIM?
>> NOW THEY WILL GO AHEAD AND
TRY TO FIGURE OUT WHY THIS
HAPPENED, WHY A GUNMAN IN HIS
20s, WENT INTO THIS PARTICULAR
SCHOOL, WITH WEAPONS, AND
STARTED KILLING KIDS.
>> YEAH, UNFORTUNATELY THIS IS
THE PLATFORM THAT PEOPLE LIKE
THIS ARE SEEKING OUT,
EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS, SOFT
TARGETS.
IF YOU WANT TO COMMIT A CRIME
LIKE THIS.
UNFORTUNATELY WE DON'T HAVE IN
PLACE RIGHT NOW THE MECHANISM TO
PROTECT OUR YOUNG AND OUR LOVED
ONES.
>> WHAT SHOULD WE BE DOING,
STEVE, AS SOMEONE WHO USED TO
WORK IN LAW ENFORCEMENT, WHAT
SHOULD WE BE DOING?
>> MATTER OF FACT, WOLF, BACK AT
VIRGINIA TECH, I RE-CREATED
VIRGINIA TECH AND HOW TO TAKE
THAT BACK.
WE HAVE TO EDUCATE THE TEACHERS.
WE ALL -- ALL OF OUR
INSTITUTIONS HAVE PLANS FOR
SOMETHING LIKE THIS, HOWEVER
WHEN IT HAPPENS, IT IS BEYOND
COMPREHENSION.
WE HAVE TO TRAIN OUR TEACHERS TO
BE ABLE TO DIRECT THE CHILDREN,
ESPECIALLY AT THIS AGE, DIRECT
THEM AND TELL THEM WHAT TO DO
BECAUSE THEY CAN'T ACT ON THEIR
OWN.
THEY ARE DEFENSELESS AGAINST
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
IT IS THE ADULTS THAT HAVE TO
PICK UP THIS PROCESS.
OUR EDUCATION SYSTEM, LAW
ENFORCEMENT, AND IT HAS GOT TO
GO BEYOND THE EDUCATION
DEPARTMENT TO THE PRESIDENT'S
OFFICE BECAUSE THE INSTITUTIONS
AND JUST IMAGINE WHAT IS BEING
PLANTED IN PEOPLE'S HEADS AND
WHY THEY'RE DOING THIS.
>> STEVE HARDY, STAND BY.
WE'LL CONTINUE THIS
CONVERSATION.
LET ME WELCOME OUR VIEWERS HERE
IN THE UNITED STATES AND AROUND
THE WORLD.
WE'RE FOLLOWING BREAKING NEWS IN
THE UNITED STATES.
I'M WOLF BLITZER IN WASHINGTON.
A HORRIFIC MASS KILLING AT A
SMALL ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
NOT LONG AGO.
AND UNFOLDED IN THE 9:00 A.M.
EASTERN HOUR.
AND NOW WE'RE BEGINNING TO GET
INFORMATION THAT CLOSE TO 30
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN KILLED IN THIS
MASS KILLING.
IN THIS MASS SHOOTING INCIDENT,
ABOUT 18 TO 20 OF THEM, WE'RE
TOLD, CHILDREN.
CHILDREN IN THIS ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, KINDERGARTEN THROUGH
FOURTH GRADE, UNDER 600 CHILDREN
IN THIS SCHOOL, OUTSIDE OF
DANBURY, CONNECTICUT, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, SMALL TOWN
POPULATION UNDER 2,000.
A LITTLE WHILE AGO, AND WE'RE
GOING TO BE HEARING FROM THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
WITHIN THE NEXT 15 MINUTES,
HE'LL BE MAKING A STATEMENT TO
THE NATION FROM THE WEST WING OF
THE WHITE HOUSE, THE PRESS
BRIEFING ROOM THERE.
WE'LL ALSO BE HEARING FROM THE
GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT,
PRESUMABLY GETTING MORE DETAILS.
BUT A LITTLE WHILE AGO WE HEARD
THIS FROM THE POLICE CHIEF IN
NEWTOWN.
>> I WILL GIVE YOU SOME VERY
BASIC AND BRIEF INFORMATION AS
WE KNOW IT NOW.
AND WE WILL SET UP REGULAR PRESS
BRIEFINGS AS APPROPRIATE.
JUST AFTER 9:30 THIS MORNING,
NEWTOWN POLICE RECEIVED A 911
CALL FOR AN EMERGENCY AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
NEWTOWN PD UPON OBTAINING
INFORMATION AS TO THE STATUS OF
THE SITUATION CONTACTED THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE AND
REQUESTED ASSISTANCE FROM STATE
POLICE AND SURROUNDING LOCAL
POLICE DEPARTMENTS.
ON AND OFF DUTY TROOPERS
RESPONDED TO THE SCHOOL AND WITH
NEWTOWN POLICE IMMEDIATELY UPON
ARRIVAL ENTERED THE SCHOOL AND
BEGAN A COMPLETE ACTIVE SHOOTER
SEARCH OF THE BUILDING.
THAT INCLUDED CHECKING EVERY
DOOR, EVERY CRACK, EVERY
CREVICE, EVERY PORTION OF THAT
SCHOOL.
OUR MAIN OBJECTIVE WAS TO
EVACUATE AS QUICKLY AND AS
EFFICIENTLY AS POSSIBLE ANY AND
ALL STUDENTS AND FACULTY IN THE
SCHOOL.
THE ENTIRE SCHOOL WAS SEARCHED.
THAT WAS ACCOMPLISHED.
A STAGING AREA WAS SET UP.
THE STUDENTS AND STAFF WERE PUT
INTO THAT STAGING AREA AND SOON
THEREAFTER THE CHILDREN AND
STAFF WERE REUNITED WITH PARENTS
AND LOVED ONES.
THERE WERE SEVERAL FATALITIES AT
THE SCENE.
BOTH STUDENTS AND STAFF.
THERE IS NO INFORMATION RELATIVE
TO THAT THAT IS BEING RELEASED
AT THIS TIME UNTIL WE MADE
COMPLETE AND PROPER
NOTIFICATION.
THE SHOOTER IS DECEASED INSIDE
THE BUILDING.
THERE IS A GREAT DEAL OF WORK
THAT IS UNDERTAKEN IMMEDIATELY
UPON LOCATING THE SHOOTER AND
THAT IS THERE IS A GREAT DEAL OF
SEARCH WARRANT ACTIVITY, A GREAT
DEAL OF LAW ENFORCEMENT ACTIVITY
BOTH IN AND OUT OF STATE TO
ENSURE WE COVER ALL THE BASES
RELATIVE TO THAT SPECIFIC
INDIVIDUAL.
SUFFICE IT TO SAY THE SCENE IS
SECURE.
THE STATE POLICE MAJOR CRIMES
SQUAD AND NEWTOWN POLICE
DEPARTMENT, DANBURY STATE
ATTORNEY AND MANY AGENCIES ARE
WORKING TOGETHER TO ANSWER ALL
THE QUESTIONS SURROUNDING
EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED.
AS MR. OCCHIOGROSSO SAID, WE'LL
KEEP YOU BRIEFED, WE'LL KEEP YOU
INFORMED ON A REGULAR BASIS.
WE'LL PUT EVERYTHING OUT VIA OUR
WEBSITE AND WITH THESE PRESS
CONFERENCES.
>> THE GUNMAN HAS BEEN
IDENTIFIED AS RYAN LANZA IN HIS
20s.
SOMEONE FROM THE TOWN OF
NEWTOWN, MARY SNOW, IS NOW
JOINING US.
MARY IS OUTSIDE THE SUSPECT'S
HOME THERE.
WE'RE GETTING THE FIRST IMAGES
NOW FROM THAT HOME.
MARY, UPDATE OUR VIEWERS ON WHAT
YOU HAVE LEARNED AS WE AWAIT THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES.
>> WOLF, WE ARE ON THE ROAD
WHERE THE LANZA HOME IS LOCATED
AND AS YOU CAN PROBABLY SEE
THERE ARE POLICE LINES BEHIND
ME.
POLICE ARE KEEPING RESIDENTS
OUT, REPORTERS OUT.
THERE ARE MORE THAN A DOZEN LAW
ENFORCEMENT VEHICLES HERE.
WE DID SEE AN AMBULANCE LEAVING
THE SCENE ABOUT 15 MINUTES AGO.
AND WHAT WE CAN TELL YOU FROM
NEIGHBORS IS THIS, THEY SAY THAT
ABOUT 11:00, ONE NEIGHBOR TOLD
US POLICE CAME AND TOLD HER THAT
THEY HAD TO EVACUATE RIGHT AWAY,
LEFT THEIR HOME, SOME PEOPLE
HAVE BEEN ABLE TO BE ESCORTED
BACK TO THEIR HOMES, BUT THEN
LEAVING AGAIN.
THIS IS AN ACTIVE CRIME SCENE,
UNCLEAR WHEN RESIDENTS WILL BE
ABLE TO RETURN TO THEIR HOMES.
IN TERMS OF WHAT PEOPLE ARE
SAYING ABOUT RYAN LANZA, TALKED
TO SEVERAL PEOPLE HERE WHO LIVE
IN THE AREA, THEY SAID THEY WERE
UNFAMILIAR WITH THE --
>> WE JUST LOST OUR CONNECTION
WITH MARY SNOW.
BUT WE'LL RECONNECT WITH HER.
DAVID ARIOSO, ONE OF OUR CNN
PRODUCERS, IS ALSO ON THE SCENE.
DAVID, WHERE EXACTLY ARE YOU IN
NEWTOWN?
>> WOLF, I'M STANDING DIRECTLY
IN FRONT OF THE FIREHOUSE RIGHT
NOW.
AND THAT'S BEEN ESSENTIALLY USED
AS SORT OF A MAKESHIFT HOLDING
PLACE.
FOR A LOT OF THESE FAMILIES AND
CHILDREN AND PARENTS WHO
ESSENTIALLY JUST ARE TRYING TO
COPE WITH WHAT HAS TRANSPIRED, I
CAN COUNT PROBABLY AT LEAST HALF
A DOZEN EMERGENCY VEHICLES.
SO IT IS STILL VERY ACTIVE SCENE
DOWN HERE.
HELICOPTERS FLYING OVERHEAD,
FBI, ATF AND LOCAL AND STATE
OFFICIALS ARE ALL ON SCENE AS IS
THE MEDIA HERE, AS FAMILIES WALK
OUT.
MANY PEOPLE TRIED TO SPEAK WITH
THEM, BUT MANY ARE JUST
INCONSOLABLE.
YOU SEE PEOPLE WALKING OUT,
PARENTS CLUTCHING THEIR
CHILDREN, TEARS IN THEIR EYES,
SPEAKING ON CELL PHONES AND JUST
TRYING TO CONVEY THE GRAVITY OF
THE SITUATION HERE.
AND I HAD AN OPPORTUNITY TO
SPEAK WITH A LOCAL TEACHER, NOT
A TEACHER AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL WHERE THE SHOOTING TOOK
PLACE, BUT IN THE NEARBY SCHOOL
SYSTEM AND SHE SAID THE PEOPLE
MOVE HERE, OFTEN FOR THE
SCHOOLS, SO YOU HAVE PEOPLE
COMING FROM IN AND AROUND THE
STATE, FOR THE QUALITY OF THE
EDUCATION THAT STUDENTS GET IN
THIS AREA.
AND SO IT BECAME SUCH A SHOCK
WHEN YOU SEE SOMETHING LIKE THIS
TRANSPIRE.
IT IS -- IT LEAVES YOU AT A LOSS
FOR WORDS, BOTH WHAT SHE SAID
AND IN MY OWN REPORTING HERE,
JUST NOT SOMETHING THAT YOU'RE
ACCUSTOMED TO, TO BE REPORTING
ON, ON THIS MANY FATALITIES OF
CHILDREN AT THAT AGE AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WOLF?
>> WE'RE GETTING THIS HORRIFIC
INFORMATION FROM A SOURCE CLOSE
TO THE INVESTIGATION, DAVID, I
WANT TO BE PRECISE WITH OUR
VIEWERS, THE SUSPECT IN THIS
CASE, RYAN LANZA, IN HIS 20s,
FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WE'RE
TOLD THAT THE SUSPECT'S MOTHER
WAS A TEACHER AT THIS SMALL
SCHOOL, OF SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
AND SHE, WE'RE TOLD BY THIS
SOURCE, HAS BEEN SHOT AND KILLED
IN THIS INCIDENT.
WHAT A HORRIFIC, HORRIFIC
DEVELOPMENT.
ALL OF A SUDDEN, WE'RE BEGINNING
TO GET A CONNECTION BETWEEN RYAN
LANZA, THE SHOOTER IN THIS CASE,
HE HIMSELF DIED AT THE SCENE.
WE DON'T KNOW PRECISELY THE
CIRCUMSTANCES, HOW HE DIED, BUT
WE KNOW HE'S DEAD.
RYAN LANZA WENT INTO THIS
SCHOOL, STARTED SHOOTING
CHILDREN AND ADULTS, CLOSE TO 30
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN KILLED.
WE'RE TOLD MAYBE 18 OR 20 OF
THEM CHILDREN.
AND NOW WE'RE TOLD THAT RYAN
LANZA'S MOTHER, A TEACHER AT
THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, WAS SHOT
AND KILLED HERSELF.
DAVID, I WANT YOU TO HOLD ON FOR
A SECOND, BECAUSE YOU'RE OUTSIDE
THAT FIREHOUSE, INSIDE THE
FIREHOUSE, TRYING TO COMFORT
THESE FAMILIES AS RABBI SHA
SHAUL PRAVER, HAS A SMALL
CONGREGATION IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, RABBI, ARE YOU
SUCCEEDING, ARE YOU ABLE TO
COMFORT SOME OF THE PARENTS WHO
ARE INSIDE, SOME OF WHOM MAY
HAVE LOST THEIR CHILDREN?
>> VERY MUCH IN SHOCK.
IT IS VERY, VERY DIFFICULT.
SOME OF THEM DO NOT KNOW THE
CONDITION OF THEIR CHILDREN AT
THE MOMENT.
WE'RE AWAITING -- IT IS TERRIBLE
ANXIETY.
SOME OF THEM, WE HOPE, WILL
SURVIVE.
THEY'RE AT HOSPITALS AND THE
GOVERNOR WILL COME BACK AND
PROVIDE US MORE SPECIFIC
INFORMATION AT 3:00 OR AROUND
THEN ON THEIR CONDITION.
IT IS VERY HARD TO CONSOLE
PARENTS IN THIS SITUATION, BUT
WE'RE TRYING AND MEMBERS OF OUR
CONGREGATION, PSYCHOLOGISTS,
SOCIAL WORKERS, HAVE COME
IMMEDIATELY TO TRY TO HELP.
>> RABBI, WHAT DO YOU SAY TO
PARENTS WHO MAY HAVE ALREADY
BEEN TOLD THAT THEIR LITTLE
DAUGHTER OR LITTLE SON WAS
KILLED?
>> THERE IS NO THEOLOGICAL
ANSWER TO THIS.
YOU AHAVE TO HUG THEM AND JUST E
WITH THEM AND CRY WITH THEM.
>> ARE ANY OF THESE FAMILIES
MEMBERS OF YOUR CONGREGATION IN
NEWTOWN?
>> WE'RE AWAITING FOR THE NEWS
ON ONE CHILD, NOAH, THAT'S HIS
NAME, AND HE'S A FIRST GRADER.
AND HIS CLASSROOM WAS NEAR THE
PRINCIPAL'S OFFICE, SO WE'RE
WORRIED ABOUT THAT.
AND WE'RE AWAITING TO SEE IF HE
SURVIVED THE ATTACK.
>> HOW MANY PARENTS, RABBI, ARE
INSIDE THAT FIREHOUSE BEING
CONSOLED RIGHT NOW, AWAITING
WORD ON THE FATE OF THEIR LITTLE
CHILDREN?
>> I'M SORRY, I DIDN'T HEAR THE
QUESTION.
>> I SAID, HOW MANY PARENTS, HOW
MANY FAMILY MEMBERS ARE INSIDE
THAT FIREHOUSE WHERE YOU ARE
RIGHT NOW?
>> I WOULD SAY AT LEAST 30
ADULTS ARE HERE, SO YOU HAVE
PARENTS AND THEN THEIR PARENTS
ARE WITH THEM, SUPPORTING THEM.
SO THERE IS AT LEAST 30, PERHAPS
EVEN MORE THERE.
HARD TO KNOW EXACTLY, YOU KNOW,
WHO IS AWAITING THE NEWS AND WHO
IS THERE AS A FRIEND, SO IT IS
HARD TO GIVE A PRECISE NUMBER.
BUT THE ROOM IS PRETTY FULL.
>> AND THEY'RE GETTING THE
INFORMATION DIRECTLY FROM
GOVERNOR MALLOY?
>> I DON'T REALLY KNOW HOW THAT
ALL WORKS.
I JUST KNOW THAT THE GOVERNOR
BRIEFED US ALL.
AND SAID THAT HE WAS GOING TO
TELL US AS SOON AS HE FOUND
ANYTHING OUT AND THAT HE SAID HE
WOULD BE BACK, YOU KNOW, AROUND
3:00.
SO I DON'T KNOW IF IT IS
SPECIFICALLY THE GOVERNOR THAT
IS PROVIDING ANY INFORMATION OR
NOT.
>> RABBI PRAVER OF CONGREGATION
OF ISRAEL OUT OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, HE'S IN THAT
FIREHOUSE, HE'S TRYING TO
CONSOLE SOME OF THESE PARENTS
WHO MAY HAVE LOST CHILDREN IN
THIS MASS SHOOTING TODAY AT THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
RABBI, WE'LL CONTINUE OUR
CONVERSATION.
WHAT A PAINFUL CONVERSATION IT
IS.
I'M SURE IT MUST BE SO PAINFUL
FOR YOU TO BE WITH THESE FAMILY
MEMBERS, WITH THESE PARENTS OF
CHILDREN WHO MAY HAVE BEEN
KILLED IN THIS MASS MURDER.
THAT'S WHAT WE HAVE TO CALL IT.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI IS ON THE SCENE
FOR US AS WELL.
SUSAN, ARE YOU GETTING MORE
INFORMATION ON WHAT HAPPENED?
>> YES, WOLF.
I HAVE SOME NEW INFORMATION TO
REPORT NOW FROM TWO LAW
ENFORCEMENT SOURCES THAT AMONG
THE DEAD IS THE MOTHER OF THE
SHOOTER IN THIS CASE.
THE MOTHER OF THE SHOOTER IS
ALSO DEAD.
SHE IS A TEACHER AT THE SCHOOL.
NOW, WE DON'T HAVE CONFIRMED
WHETHER SHE WAS FOUND DEAD AT
THE SCHOOL, OR AT SOME OTHER
LOCATION.
BUT TWO SOURCES TELL US THAT
SHE, TOO, IS AMONG THE DEAD.
ALSO SOME ADDITIONAL NEW
INFORMATION TO REPORT TO YOU,
WOLF, IS THAT THE SHOOTER, RYAN
LANZA, IS 24 YEARS OLD, 24 YEARS
OLD.
TO REMIND OUR VIEWERS.
HE WAS FOUND DEAD AT THE SCENE,
IN A CLASSROOM.
AND ADDITIONALLY HE WAS FOUND
WITH AT LEAST TWO WEAPONS.
I AM HEARING THERE MAY BE EVEN
MORE WEAPONS THAT WERE FOUND.
AND ALSO AS WE HAVE PREVIOUSLY
REPORTED, ANOTHER PERSON IS
BEING QUESTIONED BY POLICE IN
CONNECTION WITH THIS SHOOTING,
BUT WE HAVE NO ADDITIONAL
INFORMATION ON THAT AT THIS TIME
TO REPORT.
WOLF?
>> IS THE WORKING ASSUMPTION,
AND I KNOW THIS INFORMATION IS
PRELIMINARY, SUBJECT TO CHANGE,
IS THE WORKING ASSUMPTION THERE
AMONG LAW ENFORCEMENT, SUSAN,
THAT RYAN LANZA, AFTER OPENING
FIRE, KILLING ALL THESE PEOPLE,
TOOK HIS OWN LIFE?
>> Reporter: THAT IS THE WORKING
ASSUMPTION HERE.
BUT WE DON'T HAVE THAT CONFIRMED
INFORMATION THAT HE TOOK HIS OWN
LIFE.
BUT THAT CERTAINLY IS THE
WORKING THEORY HERE.
AND SO THEY HAVE A LOT OF PIECES
TO PUT TOGETHER.
WE ALSO KNOW, FOR EXAMPLE, THAT
AUTHORITIES HAVE BEEN EXECUTING
A SEARCH WARRANT AT RYAN LANZA'S
HOME.
AND THEY HAVE BEEN DOING THAT
FOR QUITE SOME TIME NOW.
WE HAVE NO INFORMATION YET ABOUT
WHAT KIND OF INFORMATION THEY
HAVE FOUND.
FOR EXAMPLE, HAD THEY FOUND ANY
ADDITIONAL WEAPONS AT THE HOUSE.
IT IS VERY LIKELY IF HE HAD A
COMPUTER THERE, THEY CERTAINLY
WOULD HAVE SEIZED THAT AND THE
HARD DRIVE AND WOULD BE HARD AT
WORK EXAMINING THAT.
SO COMMON THAT SO MANY OF US
HAVE COMPUTERS THESE DAYS.
AND SO WE'RE WAITING FOR ANOTHER
UPDATE, WE HOPE TO GET MORE
INFORMATION.
OF COURSE, IN THE COMING
MINUTES, HOURS, WE'LL HAVE TO
SEE.
AND AS YOU KNOW, THE GOVERNOR
WILL ALSO BE HOLDING A NEWS
CONFERENCE, SCHEDULED IN LESS
THAN AN HOUR FROM NOW, EXPECTED
TO HAPPEN AROUND 3:30 OR SO,
WOLF.
>> AND IN THE NEXT FEW MINUTES
WE'LL BE HEARING FROM PRESIDENT
OBAMA AT THE WHITE HOUSE AS
WELL.
BUT, SUSAN, QUICKLY, I WANT TO
BE PRECISE ON THIS, IS IT YOUR
INFORMATION THAT THE SHOOTER,
RYAN LANZA, WENT TO THE SCHOOL
AND AMONG OTHERS ACTUALLY SHOT
HIS OWN MOTHER THERE, THAT SHE
IS A TEACHER AT THIS SCHOOL, AND
YOU'RE NOW REPORTING SHE WAS
SHOT AND KILLED.
I ASSUME HE MUST HAVE SHOT HER,
BUT CORRECT ME IF I AM WRONG.
>> Reporter: YOU KNOW, THE ONLY
INFORMATION WE HAVE NOW IS THAT
HIS MOTHER IS A TEACHER AT THE
SCHOOL.
AND SHE WAS -- SHE HAS BEEN
FOUND DEAD.
INTERESTINGLY WE DON'T HAVE OUR
LAW ENFORCEMENT SOURCES TELLING
US THAT SHE IS AMONG THE DEAD AT
THE SCHOOL.
ONLY THAT SHE IS DEAD.
>> WHAT A HORRIFIC STORY.
SUSAN, I KNOW YOU'LL BE WORKING
YOUR SOURCES, GETTING MORE
INFORMATION.
MARY SNOW IS WORK HER SOURCE.
SHE'S OUTSIDE THE SUSPECT'S HOME
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE'LL CHECK BACK WITH HER.
DAVID ARIOSTO, OUR PRODUCER ON
THE SCENE, WE'LL CHECK BACK WITH
HIM.
I WANT TO GO TO OUR CHIEF WHITE
HOUSE CORRESPONDENT JESSICA
YELLIN IN THE WHITE HOUSE
BRIEFING ROOM RIGHT NOW,
AWAITING THE PRESIDENT.
SET THE SCENE OVER THERE.
MOMENTARILY HE'LL BE WALKING
OUT, MAKING A STATEMENT,
JESSICA.
>> THAT'S RIGHT, WOLF.
WE JUST GOT THE TWO-MINUTE
WARNING HERE IN THE WHITE HOUSE
FOR THE PRESIDENT TO ENTER THE
PRESS BRIEFING ROOM HERE AND
ADDRESS THIS SHOOTING.
TRAGICALLY WE HAVE ALL TOO MUCH
EXPERIENCE OF THE PRESIDENT
SPEAKING TO THE NATION AFTER
SHOOTING RAMPAGES SUCH AS THIS
ONE.
AND IN THESE INSTANCES HE
GENERALLY -- HE OFTEN TRIES TO
BRING IT TO A PERSONAL LEVEL,
TALK ABOUT THAT IT IS LIKE AS A
FATHER, TO RELATE TO WHAT -- TO
THE EXPERIENCE THAT PARENTS ARE
FEELING ACROSS THE COUNTRY RIGHT
NOW, WATCHING THIS STORY UNFOLD,
AND TRY TO TELL A STORY FROM
INSIDE THAT SCHOOL, USUALLY
TRIES TO FIND A STORY OF HEROISM
IF HE CAN, TO REASSURE THE
NATION THAT THERE ARE POSITIVE
STORIES OF AMERICAN RESILIENCE,
BUT THIS IS SUCH A GRIM DAY, IT
IS A HARD ONE FOR THE PRESIDENT,
NO DOUBT, AND FOR THE WHITE
HOUSE HERE, WOLF.
THE PRESIDENT FOUND OUT ABOUT
THIS AT 10:30 THIS MORNING FROM
HIS DIRECTOR OF HOMELAND
SECURITY.
HE'S RECEIVED UPDATES THROUGHOUT
THE DAY.
HE SPOKE TO THE FBI DIRECTOR, TO
THE CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR, AND
HAS BEEN BRIEFED CONSISTENTLY.
THE WHITE HOUSE HAS ADMONISHED
US NOT TO TALK ABOUT POLICY AND
GUN CONTROL ISSUES TODAY.
THIS IS A DAY FOR GRIEVING AND
CONCERN FOR THE FAMILIES OF
THOSE INVOLVED.
AND I EXPECT THE PRESIDENT TO
COME OUT HERE AND MAKE SOME
BRIEF REMARKS, WOLF, MUCH MORE
PERSONAL IN NATURE.
WOLF?
>> WE JUST HAVE GOTTEN WORD,
RELEASE FROM THE WHITE HOUSE,
THAT THE PRESIDENT HAS ORDERED
ALL FLAGS FLYING AT HALF-STAFF
AT THE WHITE HOUSE, ALL U.S.
INSTITUTIONS, PUBLIC GROUNDS,
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
THERE YOU SEE THE FLAG OVER THE
WHITE HOUSE FLYING AT HALF-STAFF
RIGHT NOW IN HIS ORDER.
HE SAYS I ALSO DIRECT THAT THE
FLAG SHALL BE FLOWN AT
HALF-STAFF FOR THE SAME LENGTH
UNTIL DECEMBER 18th, 2012, SAME
LENGTH OF TIME AT ALL U.S.
EMBASSIES.
HERE IS THE PRESIDENT.
>> I OFFERED GOVERNOR MALLOY MY
CONDOLENCES ON BEHALF OF THE
NATION.
AND MADE IT CLEAR HE WILL HAVE
EVERY SINGLE RESOURCE THAT HE
NEEDS TO INVESTIGATE THIS
HEINOUS CRIME, CARE FOR THE
VICTIMS, COUNSEL THEIR FAMILIES.
WE HAVE ENDURED TOO MANY OF
THESE TRAGEDIES IN THE PAST FEW
YEARS.
AND EACH TIME I LEARN THE NEWS,
I REACT NOT AS A PRESIDENT, BUT
AS ANYBODY ELSE WOULD, AS A
PARENT.
AND THAT WAS ESPECIALLY TRUE
TODAY.
I KNOW THERE IS NOT A PARENT IN
AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM, BIRTHDAYS,
GRADUATIONS, WEDDINGS, KIDS OF
THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS, MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES TO HELPING
OUR CHILDREN FULFILL THEIR
DREAMS.
SO OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN TODAY
FOR THE PARENTS AND
GRANDPARENTS, SISTERS AND
BROTHERS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN, AND FOR THE FAMILIES
OF THE ADULTS WHO WERE LOST.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN FOR THE
PARENTS OF THE SURVIVORS AS
WELL.
FOR AS BLESSED AS THEY ARE TO
HAVE THEIR CHILDREN HOME
TONIGHT, THEY KNOW THAT THEIR
CHILDREN'S INNOCENCE HAS BEEN
TORN AWAY FROM THEM TOO EARLY.
AND THERE ARE NO WORDS THAT WILL
EASE THEIR PAIN.
AS A COUNTRY WE HAVE BEEN
THROUGH THIS TOO MANY TIMES.
WHETHER IT IS AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN, OR A SHOPPING
MALL IN OREGON, OR A TEMPLE IN
WISCONSIN, OR A MOVIE THEATER IN
AURORA OR A STREET CORNER IN
CHICAGO, THESE NEIGHBORHOODS ARE
OUR NEIGHBORHOODS, AND THESE
CHILDREN ARE OUR CHILDREN.
AND WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO COME
TOGETHER AND TAKE MEANINGFUL
ACTION TO PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS, REGARDLESS OF THE
POLITICS.
THIS EVENING MICHELLE AND I WILL
DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT IN
AMERICA WILL DO, WHICH IS HUG
OUR CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER,
AND WE'LL TELL THEM THAT WE LOVE
THEM, AND WE'LL REMIND EACH
OTHER HOW DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE
ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT AND THEY NEED ALL OF US
RIGHT NOW.
IN THE HARD DAYS TO COME, THE
COMMUNITY NEEDS US TO BE AT OUR
BEST AS AMERICANS, AND I WILL DO
EVERYTHING IN MY POWER AS
PRESIDENT TO HELP.
BECAUSE WHILE NOTHING CAN FILL
THE SPACE OF A LOST CHILD OR
LOVED ONE, ALL OF US CAN EXTEND
THE HAND TO THOSE IN NEED, TO
REMIND THEM THAT WE ARE THERE
FOR THEM, THAT WE ARE PRAYING
FOR THEM, THAT THE LOVE THEY
FELT FOR THOSE THEY LOST ENDURES
NOT JUST IN THEIR MEMORIES, BUT
ALSO IN OURS.
MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF THE
VICTIMS AND IN THE WORDS OF
SCRIPTURE, HEAL THE
BROKEN-HEARTED AND BIND UP THEIR
WOUNDS.
>> VERY, VERY EMOTIONAL MOMENT
FOR THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES.
DARE I SAY FOR ALL OF AMERICA.
MUCH OF THE WORLD RIGHT NOW.
YOU DON'T OFTEN SEE THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
SHOWING SUCH EMOTION, WIPING
AWAY TEARS AS HE SPEAKS OF THESE
LITTLE KIDS, 5 TO 10-YEAR-OLD
KIDS, THE MAJORITY OF THE
VICTIMS WHO WERE KILLED IN THIS
MASS SHOOTING IN CONNECTICUT
TODAY.
GOT TO TELL YOU, I COVERED A LOT
OF PRESIDENTS, I HAVEN'T SEEN A
PRESIDENT EMERGE AS EMOTIONALLY
CHARGED AND THIS IS A PRESIDENT
WHO HAS TWO DAUGHTERS, HE SENDS
TO SCHOOL EVERY DAY, LIKE
MILLIONS OF OTHER PARENTS ALL
OVER THE COUNTRY, HOW MUCH THEY
CAN IDENTIFY WITH WHAT IS GOING
ON RIGHT NOW, THIS INSANITY THAT
HAS OCCURRED IN THIS SMALL
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
CONNECTICUT.
TODAY, JOHN KING IS JOINING WITH
US MORE INFORMATION.
WE HAVE COVERED PRESIDENTS, NOT
OFTEN -- DARE I SAY, I DON'T
REMEMBER A TIME I'VE SEEN A
PRESIDENT START LITERALLY CRYING
LIKE THAT IN THE MIDDLE OF A
MAJOR STATEMENT.
>> AS THE PRESIDENT HIMSELF
NOTED, WOLF, I THINK HE WAS
ADDRESSING THE NATION MORE AS A
FATHER THAN AS A PRESIDENT.
AND I CAN -- I'VE BEEN TEXTING
MY TEENAGE DAUGHTER ALL
AFTERNOON.
I GET WHAT THE PRESIDENT SAYS
ABOUT HUGGING YOUR CHILDREN A
LITTLE TIGHTER TONIGHT.
THIS IS INCOMPREHENSIBLE AND
THAT'S ONE REASON THE PRESIDENT
WAS SO SAD, AS HE DELIVERED THAT
STATEMENT THERE.
AS WE GET MORE INFORMATION,
WOLF, IT BECOMES MORE
INCOMPREHENSIBLE.
I'M TOLD BY FEDERAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT SOURCE THAT MOST OF
THOSE KILLED WERE KILLED IN THE
CLASSROOM OF THE ALLEGED
SHOOTER'S MOTHER WHO WAS A
TEACHER AT THE SCHOOL, NANCY
LANZA.
AND THAT HE WENT INTO THAT
CLASSROOM AND, AGAIN THIS IS
ACCORDING TO POLICE AT THE
SCENE, REPORTING BACK TO FEDERAL
LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS HERE,
SHOT AND KILLED HIS MOTHER AND
THEN SHOT AND KILLED STUDENTS
AND THIS SOURCE SAYING MOST OF
THOSE KILLED WERE KILLED IN THAT
CLASSROOM AND SHE WAS A
KINDERGARTEN TEACHER AT THE
SCHOOL, WOLF.
THAT IS AGAIN THE
INCOMPREHENSIBLE INFORMATION
WE'RE GETTING AS MORE AND MORE
DETAILS OF THE INVESTIGATION
EMERGE.
>> WE'RE GETTING THIS
INFORMATION, JOHN, AS WELL, FROM
OUR JUSTICE PRODUCER, TERRY
FRIEDEN, LET ME BE PRECISE IN
WHAT HE HAS LEARNED, SENIOR LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIAL FAMILIAR
WITH THE INVESTIGATION, HE TELLS
US, SAYS A BROTHER OF THE
SHOOTER, THE ALLEGED SHOOTER,
WAS FOUND DEAD IN THE
RESIDENTIAL LOCATION, NEAR
SEARCHED IN HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY,
ACROSS THE RIVER FROM NEW YORK
CITY.
IN ADDITION, THE MOTHER OF THE
ALLEGED SHOOTER WAS FOUND DEAD
IN THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE FATHER WHO WAS DIVORCED FROM
LANZA'S MOTHER LIVES ELSEWHERE
IN CONNECTICUT.
THE OFFICIAL SAID.
THE OFFICIAL DECLINED TO PROVIDE
FURTHER DETAILS.
SO, JOHN, NOW WE'RE LEARNING NOT
ONLY WAS THE MOTHER FOUND DEAD,
AS YOU'VE BEEN REPORTING INSIDE
THE SMALL ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
AND MANY OF THE CHILDREN WERE
WHO WERE KILLED WERE IN HER
CLASSROOM, SHE WAS A TEACHER AT
THIS SCHOOL, BUT THE BROTHER OF
THE ALLEGED SHOOTER WAS FOUND
DEAD IN A RESIDENTIAL LOCATION
IN HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY.
THIS HAS BEEN OBVIOUSLY VERY,
VERY OFF, EVEN MORE AWFUL THAN
YOU CAN IMAGINE.
>> AND YOU WERE SPEAKING, WOLF,
I'M SORRY, A SHORT TIME AGO TO
THE SCHOOL SECURITY EXPERT WHO
PREDICTED SOMETHING SIMILAR TO
THIS, SAID AS MORE DETAILS
EMERGE, YOU'RE LIKELY TO FIND A
PROFILE OF SOMEBODY WHO WAS
HAVING A VERY TROUBLED ISSUES IN
HIS OR HER FAMILY LIFE.
NOW WE KNOW THE SHOOTER, OF
COURSE, 24-YEAR-OLD, I BELIEVE,
YOUNG MAN, RYAN LANZA, ACCORDING
TO POLICE AT THE SCENE AND YOU
HAVE FROM TERRY FRIEDEN'S
REPORTING, A BROTHER KILLED, HIS
MOTHER WAS A TEACHER AT THE
SCHOOL, AND IS BELIEVED THAT SHE
WAS THE PRIMARY TARGET,
ACCORDING TO FEDERAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS AND HE
SHOT HER AND THEN SHOT CHILDREN
IN HER CLASSROOM AT THE SCHOOL,
MOST OF THE DEATHS I'M TOLD BY
THE LAW ENFORCEMENT SOURCE
OCCURRED THERE IN THAT ONE
CONCENTRATED AREA OF THE SCHOOL.
AND THE POLICE WILL TRY TO PUT
THIS TOGETHER.
AND OBVIOUSLY THERE WILL BE
DETAILED INVESTIGATION INTO WHAT
THING OR WHAT THINGS MAY HAVE
BEEN THE TRIGGER HERE FOR THIS
HORRIFIC EVENT.
AND THAT IS PART OF THE
INVESTIGATIVE DETAIL THAT WE'LL
TRY TO PUT TOGETHER, AND IT IS
ALWAYS THE BIG QUESTION, THE
PRESIDENT JUST ASKED IT QUITE
POIGNANTLY AND I THINK PARENTS
AROUND THE COUNTRY AS WELL AS
ALL THOSE LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS WERE SHOWING ON OUR
SCREENS AT THE SCENE TODAY WILL
BE ASKING VERY SHORT QUESTION,
WHY.
>> WE DON'T KNOW.
WE HAVE NO IDEA, THOUGH I
SUSPECT WE'LL LEARN A LOT MORE
IN THE COMING MINUTES, HOURS AND
CERTAINLY DAYS.
JOHN, STAND BY.
JESSICA YELLIN IS OUR CHIEF
WHITE HOUSE CORRESPONDENT.
YOU WERE IN THE BRIEFING ROOM
WHEN THE PRESIDENT DELIVERED THE
POWERFUL, VERY EMOTIONAL
STATEMENT.
WE SAW HIM REPEATEDLY PAUSING,
TRYING TO CONTROL HIMSELF,
WIPING AWAY TEARS AS HE SPOKE TO
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE.
>> WOLF, I'VE SIMPLY NEVER SEEN
THE PRESIDENT THAT EMOTIONAL.
PUBLICLY HE'S NEVER CRIED LIKE
THAT IN MY PRESENCE.
HE WAS CONSISTENTLY WIPING AWAY
TEARS AS YOU SAY.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS, HE CALLED
THEM, AND POINTED OUT, AGAIN, AS
HE ALWAYS DOES, DURING THESE
INSTANCES, BUT IT SEEMED TO
REALLY HIT HOME FOR HIM HERE,
THE WHITE HOUSE, AND FOR SO MANY
OF HIS AIDES THAT WE SAW
ACTUALLY HOLDING HANDS AND
CRYING BY THE SIDE, THAT HE IS A
PARENT WHO CAN NOW GO HOME AND
HUG HIS CHILDREN TONIGHT, BUT
THESE FAMILIES CANNOT.
OBVIOUSLY THIS IS NOT A STORY
ABOUT THE WHITE HOUSE.
BUT WHEN HE SPEAKS AS THE
CONSOLAR IN CHIEF, IT IS SORT OF
REPRESENTATIVE OF WHAT SO MANY
PEOPLE AROUND THE COUNTRY ARE
EXPERIENCING TONIGHT AND THIS
IS, IN A WAY, ONE OF THOSE
STORIES THAT WRENCHES EVERYBODY
OUT OF THE MOMENT, OUT OF THE
STORIES THAT WE HAVE BEEN
COVERING, AND REMINDS US ALL
THAT WHATEVER PARTISAN POLITICS
WE HAVE BEEN GOING THROUGH IN
REPORTING ON, THIS IS A TIME TO
JUST PAUSE AND APPRECIATE OUR
FAMILIES, APPRECIATE WHAT WE DO
HAVE, COMFORT THOSE WHO ARE
STRUGGLING RIGHT NOW AND GOING
THROUGH LOSS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS CLEARLY
STRUGGLING TO DO THAT HIMSELF
RIGHT NOW BECAUSE HE IS CLEARLY
SHAKEN BY THIS.
PERSONALLY.
AND I WOULD POINT OUT THAT HE
DID MAKE A VEILED REFERENCE TO
TRYING TO TAKE SOME ACTION IN
THE WAKE OF THIS.
HE SAID WHATEVER OUR POLITICS,
WE HAVE TO DO SOMETHING TO MAKE
SURE THESE TRAGEDIES STOP.
WE WILL HAVE TO FOLLOW UP ON
ANOTHER TIME TO SEE EXACTLY WHAT
THAT MEANS FOR HIM, WOLF.
>> AND THERE IS NO DOUBT THAT
THE PRESIDENT IS EMOTIONALLY
MOVED.
I SUPPOSE HE'S ANXIOUS TO GO TO
CONNECTICUT, CONSOLE THE
PARENTS.
WE'RE AWAITING WORD FROM THE
GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT, DANNEL
MALLOY, SPEAKING MOMENTARILY.
LET'S TAKE THIS QUICK BREAK.
WE'LL RESUME THE BREAKING NEWS
COVERAGE RIGHT AFTER THIS.
[ Male Announcer ] Alka-Seltzer
Plus PRESENTS THE Cold Truth.
I HAVE A COLD,
AND I TOOK NYQUIL,
BUT I'M STILL "STUBBED" UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT DOESN'T HAVE A DECONGESTANT.
NO WAY.
[ Male Announcer ] SORRY.
Alka-Seltzer Plus FIGHTS
YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A FAST ACTING
DECONGESTANT
TO RELIEVE YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
[ sighs ] THANKS!
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus.
♪ OH
WHAT A RELIEF IT IS! ♪
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
AND SAVE $1
VISIT Alka-Seltzer ON FACEBOOK.
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
Social Security are just numbers
thinkin a budget.d...
Well, we worked hard for those
benefits.
We earned them.
And if Washington tries to cram
decisions about the future...
of these programs into a last
minute budget deal...
we'll all pay the price.
AARP is fighting to protect
seniors with responsible...
solutions that strengthen
Medicare and...
Social Security for generations
to come.
We can do better than a last
minute deal...
that would hurt all of us.
HUMANS -- SOMETIMES LIFE
TRIPS US UP.
AND SOMETIMES,
WE TRIP OURSELVES UP,
BUT THAT'S OKAY.
AT LIBERTY MUTUAL INSURANCE
WE CAN "UNTRIP" YOU
AS YOU GO THROUGH
YOUR LIFE
WITH PERSONALIZED POLICIES
AND DISCOUNTS WHEN YOU
NEED THEM MOST.
JUST CALL...
AND SPEAK WITH A LICENSED
REPRESENTATIVE
ABOUT SAVING ON YOUR POLICY
WHEN YOU GET MARRIED,
MOVE INTO A NEW HOUSE...
[Crash!]
OR ADD A CAR TO YOUR POLICY.
DON'T FORGET TO ASK ABOUT
SAVING UP TO 10%
WHEN YOU COMBINE
YOUR AUTO AND HOME INSURANCE
WITH LIBERTY MUTUAL.
SECURITY, COVERAGE,
AND SAVINGS.
ALL THE THINGS HUMANS NEED
TO MAKE OUR BEAUTIFULLY
IMPERFECT WORLD
A LITTLE LESS IMPERFECT.
CALL...
AND LOCK IN YOUR RATE
FOR 12 MONTHS.
LIBERTY MUTUAL INSURANCE.
RESPONSIBILITY.
WHAT'S YOUR POLICY?
♪
>>> HORRIFIC PICTURES COMING IN
FROM CONNECTICUT, FROM A SMALL
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WHERE A
SHOOTER, RYAN LANZA, 24 YEARS
OLD, WENT INTO THAT SCHOOL, AND
STARTED KILLING PEOPLE.
WE ARE NOW TOLD ACCORDING TO LAW
ENFORCEMENT AUTHORITIES THE
SUSPECTED GUNMAN SHOT HIS
MOTHER, A TEACHER, AT THE
SCHOOL, AND THEN OPENED FIRE ON
CHILDREN IN THAT CLASSROOM AND
OTHERS INSIDE, WE'RE TOLD, CLOSE
TO 30 PEOPLE HAVE BEEN CONFIRMED
KILLED.
MAYBE 18 OR 20 OF THEM CHILDREN.
WE'RE ALSO TOLD THAT THE MOTHER
OF RYAN LANZA, NANCY LANZA, WAS
SHOT AND KILLED IN THIS
CLASSROOM AS WELL AS EARLIER THE
BROTHER OF RYAN LANZA IN A
RESIDENTIAL AREA OF HOBOKEN, NEW
JERSEY.
WHAT CAN WE SAY?
THIS KIND OF SITUATION IS
POWERFUL AND AWFUL AND WE JUST
SAW THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES MAKE A -- DELIVER A
STATEMENT TO THE AMERICAN PEOPLE
IN WHICH HE CHOKED UP.
HE HAD TO PAUSE ON SEVERAL
OCCASIONS.
HE STARTED CRYING, WIPING BACK
TEARS, SPEAKING AS A PARENT WHO
SENDS HIS TWO LITTLE GIRLS, HIS
DAUGHTERS TO SCHOOL EVERY SINGLE
DAY.
THIS IS A STORY THAT MILLIONS
AND MILLIONS OF PEOPLE ALL OVER
THE UNITED STATES WILL
APPRECIATE.
WE WANT TO WELCOME OUR VIEWERS
HERE IN THE UNITED STATES, AND
AROUND THE WORLD.
LET'S GET SOME PERSPECTIVE ON
WHAT IS GOING ON HERE.
DR. DREW IS JOINING US FROM LOS
ANGELES RIGHT NOW.
DR. DREW, WHAT CAN WE SAY?
HOW DO YOU CONSOLE PARENTS WHO
ARE GOING THROUGH A TRAGEDY, A
CRISIS LIKE THIS AT THAT
FIREHOUSE.
WE HEARD FROM THAT RABBI WHO IS
THERE, MEETING WITH THESE
PARENTS, THEY HAVE BEEN TOLD
THAT THEIR 5-YEAR-OLD,
6-YEAR-OLD, 7-YEAR-OLD HAS BEEN
KILLED.
>> WOLF, THERE ARE NO WORDS.
THERE ARE NO WORDS.
IT IS SIMPLY THE WORST
EXPERIENCE IMAGINABLE.
THERE IS NO WAY TO CONSOLE.
WE JUST HAVE TO BE PRESENT WHILE
PEOPLE GRIEVE.
WE ARE IN A NEW WORLD TODAY.
WE HAVE CROSSED OVER TO A WORLD
WHERE SOMEBODY FEELS JUSTIFIED
IN ACTING OUT THEIR RAGE BY
KILLING CHILDREN AT CLOSE RANGE.
I SPENT A LOT OF TIME IN THE
MEDIA TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHY
RANDOM ACTS OF VIOLENCE OCCUR,
WHY A KID IN OREGON SEEMS
DISCONNECTED FROM REALITY FOR A
WHILE AND DOES SENSELESS THINGS.
THIS IS SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
THIS IS SINISTER.
THIS IS SOMEBODY PURPOSEFULLY
PLANNING, GOING, KILLING HIS
FAMILY, AND KILLING SMALL
CHILDREN.
THAT'S THE WORLD WE LIVE IN
RIGHT NOW.
WE LIVE IN A WORLD WHERE PEOPLE
FEEL JUSTIFIED IN PUSHING
SOMEBODY ON A SUBWAY TRACKS AND
KILLING SMALL CHILDREN.
THIS HAS GOT TO CHANGE.
WE ALL HAVE TO BE AWARE OF THIS.
OUR CULTURE IS SICK.
THERE ARE SICK AMONGST US.
AND WE HAVE TO BEGIN TO ADDRESS
THIS.
>> IT LOOKS, DR. DREW, LIKE AS
IF WHAT HAPPENED WAS THIS
INDIVIDUAL, RYAN LANZA, 24 YEARS
OLD, WAS AT HOBOKEN, AND, YOU
KNOW, THIS IS -- IT LOOKS LIKE
THE PIECES OF THE PUZZLE ARE
BEGINNING TO COME TOGETHER, SHOT
AND KILLED HIS BROTHER.
THEN DROVE, WHAT, ABOUT 80 MILES
FROM HOBOKEN, TO NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WENT INSIDE THE
SMALL ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, AND
SHOT HIS MOTHER AND THEN OPENED
FIRE ON CHILDREN.
THIS IS SOMETHING -- YOU CAN
IMAGINE DRIVING FROM HOBOKEN TO
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, THINKING
ABOUT WHAT HE'S ABOUT TO DO.
HE WAS WELL ARMED.
HE HAD ASSAULT WEAPONS.
HE HAD A LOT OF AMMUNITION.
AND, YOU KNOW, HE'S OBVIOUSLY
DEAD.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO GET HIS SIDE
OF THE STORY, UNLESS HE LEAVES
SOME SORT OF EVIDENCE, A NOTE OR
SOMETHING TO GIVE US AN
INDICATION.
>> REALLY DOESN'T MATTER.
THIS SORT OF PURPOSEFUL,
GOAL-DIRECTED, RAGEFUL ACTION,
PEOPLE TALK ABOUT IT AS EVIL,
THIS IS TRULY IN THAT ZONE.
THIS IS PSYCHOPATHY.
THERE MUST HAVE BEEN EVIDENCE
THAT THIS WAS A PROBLEMATIC
PERSON LONG BEFORE, AND I'M
SAYING NOW, WE HAVE TO HELP
PEOPLE HELP THEM.
WE HAVE TO PREVENT PEOPLE FROM
DOING THESE THINGS.
WE HAVE TO BREAK DOWN PARENTS'
DENIALS WHO DON'T WANT TO ADMIT
THEIR KID MAY BE -- HAVE
TENDENCIES IN THIS DIRECTION.
WE MUST TAKE ACTION BEFORE
SOMETHING HORRIBLE LIKE THIS
HAPPENS.
THIS IS NOT LIKE AN OREGON,
WHERE THE KID SEEMS OUT OF
CONTEXT, DOESN'T SEEM
UNDERSTANDABLE.
THAT'S WHAT YOU CALL A PSYCHOTIC
EPISODE.
THERE MAY HAVE BEEN SOMETHING OF
THAT NATURE GOING ON HERE.
WE'LL LEARN AS WE GO ALONG, BUT
THE PURPOSEFUL, GOAL-DIRECTED
NATURE OF THESE ACTIONS SUGGEST
SOMETHING FAR WORSE, FAR MORE
SINISTER, AND FAR MORE CHRONIC.
IN OTHER WORDS, FAR MORE
POTENTIALLY PREDICTABLE.
LISTEN, I WAS THINKING ABOUT
THIS, WOLF, JUST SITTING HERE IN
THE CHAIR WAITING TO TALK TO
YOU, WHEN WE'RE TREATING -- WHEN
WE OPERATE A HOSPITAL OR IN A
TREATMENT ENVIRONMENT, WE TRY TO
OPERATE LIKE A HEALTHY FAMILY,
IN ORDER TO DECREASE THE
TENDENCIES FOR THE MOST
VULNERABLE AMONGST US, THE ONES
WE'RE TRYING TO TREAT FROM
ACTING OUT.
IT IS TIME FOR OUR GOVERNMENT
AND OUR CULTURE TO ACT LIKE A
HEALTHY FAMILY.
DIVISIVENESS IS STARTING TO HAVE
ITS EFFECT AMONGST THE MOST
VULNERABLE AMONGST US AND IT IS
TIME TO STOP.
WE HAVE TO LEAD OUR WAY OUT OF
THIS, AND WE NEED OUR LEADERS TO
BEHAVE IN A HEALTHY MANNER.
>> WE'RE AWAITING, DR. DREW, THE
GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT, DANNEL
MALLOY, HE'S BEEN INSIDE THAT
FIREHOUSE MEETING WITH PARENTS
WHOSE KIDS WERE KILLED TODAY.
FIRST GRADERS, SECOND-GRADERS,
THIRD GRADERS AND HE'S ABOUT TO
MAKE A STATEMENT THERE, HE'S
WALKING UP TO THE MICROPHONE.
MOMENTARILY WE'RE TOLD WE'LL
HEAR WHAT HE HAS TO SAY.
BUT WHAT I'M INTERESTED IN YOU
TELLING US, MAYBE YOU'LL TELL US
AFTER WE HEAR FROM THE GOVERNOR,
WHAT DO PARENTS TELL THEIR
CHILDREN TONIGHT BECAUSE THIS
IS -- THESE KINDS OF INCIDENTS,
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN WHAT HAPPENED
HERE?
>> RIGHT.
FEEL FREE TO INTERRUPT ME IF THE
GOVERNOR STARTS SPEAKING.
THE FACT IS WE HAVE TO BEGIN TO
OPERATE HEALTHY WITHIN OUR
FAMILIES, WITHIN OUR
COMMUNITIES, WITHIN OUR STATES,
WITHIN OUR GOVERNMENT.
WE HAVE TO START IN OUR FAMILIES
AND HELPING KIDS UNDERSTAND THAT
THEY'RE LOVED, THEY'RE IN A
STABLE ENVIRONMENT, WE'RE
COMMITTED TO THEM, AND WE HAVE
TO BE COMMITTED TO THEM, WE HAVE
TO BE PARENTS, AND THAT THEY ARE
SAFE.
SOMETIMES YOU MAY PICK --
DEPENDING ON THE AGE OF THE
CHILD, MAYBE THAT CHILD WILL
WANT TO TAKE ACTION, TAKE
SELF-DEFENSE CLASSES, WANT TO DO
SOMETHING WHERE THEY CAN FEEL
LIKE THEY'RE IN CONTROL OF THEIR
ENVIRONMENT.
BUT FUNDAMENTALLY, THE SAFETY
AND SECURITY AND THE COMMITMENT
TO THE FAMILY NEEDS TO BE
REASSURED.
IT IS THE HOLIDAY SEASON.
WE NEED TO LET THE KIDS HAVE
THEIR HOLIDAY SEASON.
BUT I'M TELLING YOU, WE NEED TO
OPERATE ON THE MACRO LEVEL AS
WELL AS ON THE INDIVIDUAL FAMILY
LEVEL.
WE, AS PARENTS, NEED TO TAKE A
PAGE FROM OUR LEADERS --
>> HOLD ON.
>> LET'S SEE WHAT THEY HAVE TO
SAY.
>> EARLIER TODAY A TRAGEDY OF
UNSPEAKABLE TERMS PLAYED ITSELF
OUT IN THIS COMMUNITY.
LIEUTENANT GOVERNOR AND I HAVE
BEEN SPOKEN TO AND IN AN ATTEMPT
WE MIGHT BE PREPARED FOR
SOMETHING LIKE THIS PLAYING
ITSELF OUT IN OUR STATE.
YOU CAN NEVER BE PREPARED FOR
THIS KIND OF INCIDENT.
WHAT HAS HAPPENED AND WHAT HAS
TRANSPIRED AT THAT SCHOOL
BUILDING WILL LEAVE A MARK ON
THIS COMMUNITY AND EVERY FAMILY
IMPACTED.
I ONLY ASK THAT ALL OF OUR
FELLOW CITIZENS HERE IN THE
UNITED STATES AND AROUND THE
WORLD WHO HAVE ALREADY OFFERED
THEIR ASSISTANCE REMEMBER ALL OF
THE VICTIMS IN THEIR PRAYERS.
TO ALL OF YOU IN THE MEDIA, WE
WILL DO OUR BEST TO KEEP YOU AS
INFORMED AS WE CAN.
AFTER I'M DONE SPEAKING, A
REPRESENTATIVE OF THE STATE
POLICE WILL SPEAK TO YOU AND
GIVE YOU SOME ADDITIONAL
INFORMATION.
EARLIER TODAY, A NUMBER OF OUR
CITIZENS, BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN,
HAD THEIR LIFE TAKEN AWAY FROM
THEM.
AS WELL AS ADULTS WHOSE
RESPONSIBILITY IT WAS TO EDUCATE
AND SUPERVISE THOSE CHILDREN.
THE PERPETRATOR OF THE CRIME IS
DEAD.
AS IS AN INDIVIDUAL WHO THE
PERPETRATOR LIVED WITH.
WITH THAT, I'M GOING TO TURN IT
OVER TO PAUL VANCE, WHO WILL
ANSWER OR WILL GIVE YOU SOME
ADDITIONAL INFORMATION AND THEN
LATER IN THE DAY PERHAPS WE'LL
SPEAK AGAIN.
AGAIN, I THINK ON BEHALF OF THE
PEOPLE OF THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT, WE EXTEND OUR
CONDOLENCES AS I HAVE AT THE
FIREHOUSE TO THE PARENTS OF
THESE CHILDREN, AS WELL AS THE
ADULTS THAT ARE THERE.
I WANT TO THANK THE PRESIDENT,
WHO HAS BEEN ON THE PHONE WITH
US TODAY, FOR HIS STATEMENT
RELEASED TO YOU A LITTLE WHILE
AGO AS WELL AS THE STATEMENTS HE
MADE TO ME EARLIER -- MUCH
EARLIER TODAY, AS THE HOURS
RACED BY.
AND WITH THAT, I SHOULD ALSO SAY
THAT THERE ARE A NUMBER OF
PUBLIC OFFICIALS INCLUDING THE
FIRST SELECT WOMAN WHO HAS BEEN
ON SITE THROUGHOUT THE DAY, WE
HAVE STATE REPRESENTATIVES,
STATE SENATOR, OTHER SELECT
PEOPLE WHO ARE HERE.
WE HAVE THE SUPERINTENDENT OF
THE SCHOOL WHO HAS DONE
RELATIVE TO THAT, THAT'S THE
REASON WE HAVE NOT IDENTIFIED
HIM AS OF YET, SEARCH WARRANTS,
EXAMINATION OF AREAS OF
RESIDENT'S EMPLOYMENT AND ANY
ANCILLARY THINGS THAT MAY BE
ATTACHED TO THE IDENTITY AND THE
INDIVIDUAL.
THE SCENE HAS BEEN SECURED.
MAJOR CRIME UNITS HAVE RESPONDED
AND ARE WORKING WITH SEVERAL
AGENCIES TO PROCESS THIS SCENE.
IT IS NOT A SIMPLISTIC SCENE AS
YOU CAN CERTAINLY UNDERSTAND.
WE NEED TO ESTABLISH IDENTITY,
WE NEED TO DOCUMENT THE ENTIRE
SCENE, AND SIMPLY STATED WE NEED
TO ANSWER EVERY SINGLE QUESTION
SURROUNDING EXACTLY HOW AND WHY
THIS INCIDENT OCCURRED.
AS THE GOVERNOR SAID, WE WILL BE
HERE THROUGH THE NIGHT,
CERTAINLY THROUGH THE WEEKEND
AND WE'RE NOT EVEN PUTTING A
TIME STAMP ON THIS AS TO WHEN WE
WILL COMPLETE THIS PROJECT.
WE'LL WORK WITH THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER'S OFFICE, WE HAVE TO
ESTABLISH POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATION, AND, AGAIN, A
GREAT DEAL OF WORK THAT NEEDS TO
BE DONE HERE AT THE SCHOOL.
WE'LL TAKE SOME VERY -- AGAIN,
VERY BRIEF QUESTIONS BUT
UNDERSTAND THIS IS AN ACTIVE
ONGOING CASE AND THERE ARE MANY
THINGS WE CANNOT AND WILL NOT
DISCUSS AT THIS TIME.
YES, SIR.
[ INAUDIBLE ]
>> THERE IS A SECONDARY CRIME
SCENE HERE IN NEWTOWN.
THAT IS, IN FACT, CORRECT.
THERE IS AN ADULT DECEASED AT
THAT LOCATION.
I CAN'T DISCUSS ANY FURTHER
INFORMATION ON THAT AT THIS
TIME.
THERE IS ASSISTANCE BEING LENDED
TO US BY NEW JERSEY.
I DON'T HAVE THE DETAILS ON
THAT.
SO I CAN'T ANSWER THAT.
I'M SORRY.
YES, MA'AM.
>>.
[ INAUDIBLE ]
-- THE CHILDREN WERE IN ONE
CLASSROOM AND IN ONE SPACE?
>> I CAN SIMPLY STATE THAT THE
INFORMATION THAT WE HAVE RIGHT
NOW THAT WE WANT TO PUBLICIZE
THAT THE SHOOTINGS TOOK PLACE IN
ONE SECTION OF THE SCHOOL, IN
TWO ROOMS.
THAT'S AS MUCH AS WE WANT TO GO
IN RIGHT NOW AS FAR AS LOCATION.
OUR PERSONNEL ARE DOCUMENTING
THAT ENTIRE SCENE AND WE'LL HAVE
LITERALLY EVERYTHING MAPPED OUT
IN A FINAL REPORT, AND WE'LL
REPORT THE ANSWERS TO THOSE
QUESTIONS.
RIGHT NOW I DON'T HAVE ANY MORE
DETAILS THAN THAT.
YOU HAD A QUESTION, SIR.
SOMEONE -- RIGHT NOW THERE IS
ONE SHOOTER, BUT, AGAIN, WE'RE
STILL LOOKING AT EVERY ANCILLARY
FACT AND CIRCUMSTANCE RELATED TO
THE DECEASED SHOOTER AT THE
SCENE.
YES, SIR.
[ INAUDIBLE ]
>> I DON'T HAVE THAT
INFORMATION, I'M SORRY.
[ INAUDIBLE ]
>> TO BE DETERMINED.
I DON'T HAVE THE ANSWER TO THAT
QUESTION EITHER.
THE NEXT STEP WILL BE THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER'S OFFICE WILL
ASSIST US IN ANSWERING A LOT OF
THOSE QUESTIONS, MANNER AND
CAUSE OF DEATH OF ALL OF THE
DECEA
DECEASED.
THAT'S IT.
26 DECEASED.
>> LIEUTENANT, ONCE AGAIN, THE
CHILDREN --
>> I'M SORRY, ONE INJURY.
ONE PERSON WAS INJURED, YES.
>> ONE CLASSROOM?
>> I'M SORRY?
>> WERE THE CHILDREN IN ONE
CLASSROOM?
>> ONE SECTION, ONE AREA OF THE
SCHOOL.
THAT'S THE BEST I CAN DO ON THAT
ANSWER.
I DON'T KNOW SPECIFICALLY HOW
MANY ROOMS ARE INVOLVED.
I WAS TOLD THAT THERE WERE TWO,
BUT IN ONE SECTION OF THE SCHOOL
BUILDING.
>> THE ADULTS --
>> EVERYONE WAS IN THAT SAME
SECTION OF THE BUILDING.
>> WAS THAT KINDERGARTEN.
>> THAT IS TO BE DETERMINED.
A SECTION OF THE BUILDING IS AS
FAR AS WE WANT TO GO.
[ INAUDIBLE ]
>> THAT'S TO BE DETERMINED ONCE
MORE EXAMINATIONS ARE COMPLETE.
>> -- THE SHOOTER AS WELL.
>> EXCUSE ME?
>> DOES 26 INCLUDE THE SHOOTER?
>> 26.
>> JUST AT THE SCHOOL?
>> THAT'S AT THE SCHOOL ITSELF.
THERE IS ONE MORE AS WE SAID, A
SECONDARY CRIME SCENE, A
DECEASED ADULT AT A SECONDARY
CRIME SCENE.
YES, MA'AM.
[ INAUDIBLE ]
TO BE DETERMINED.
THAT'S SOMETHING OUR
INVESTIGATORS ARE GOING TO HAVE
TO LOOK AT THOROUGHLY AND
COMPLETELY AND THAT WILL TAKE
SOME TIME TO TRY AND ANSWER THAT
QUESTION.
[ INAUDIBLE ]
WE HAVEN'T ESTABLISHED ANY OF
THAT, MA'AM.
WE HAVE NOT MADE ANY POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATIONS.
WE'RE WORKING ON THAT.
THERE IS PRELIMINARY
IDENTIFICATIONS MADE, BUT WE
HAVE, AS I SAID, A GREAT DEAL OF
WORK.
THAT'S ONE THING WE HAVE TO DO
IS ESTABLISH POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATION ON ALL THE
DECEASED AND THAT'S A TIME
CONSUMING PROCESS.
>> DO WE KNOW THE AGES OF THE
VICTIMS?
THE AGES, THE AGE RANGE?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
IT IS A K THROUGH 4 ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
OKAY.
>> WHEN POLICE WENT INTO THE
SCHOOL, WERE THERE SCHOOL SHOTS
BEING FIRED AT THAT TIME?
>> THAT I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW THE TIME SEQUENCE.
THAT WILL BE SOMETHING WE WILL
PROVIDE.
WHAT I WOULD LIKE TO DO IS --
NO, WE DID NOT.
WHAT I WOULD LIKE TO DO THEN IS
TELL YOU THIS IS A BRIEFING.
WE'LL BE BACK IN 60 MINUTES.
MYSELF AND THE LIEUTENANT FROM
NEWTOWN WILL BE BACK IN 60
MINUTES, SEE IF THERE IS ANY
MORE DETAILS.
I HAVE?
OF T
SOME OF THE QUESTIONS YOU POSED.
I'LL TRY TO GET ANSWERS TO
PROVIDE YOU WITH INFORMATION.
THAT WILL BE JUST ABOUT 20 TO
5:00, QUARTER TO 5:00.
>> YOU SAY THAT'S 20 CHILDREN, 6
ADULTS AND THE SHOOTER, CORRECT?
>> 20 CHILDREN, 6 ADULTS IN THE
FACILITY, PLUS THE SHOOTER,
THAT'S 27, AND THEN A SECONDARY
SCENE WITH AN ADDITIONAL ADULT
VICTIM AT THAT SECONDARY SCENE.
>> 28.
>> OKAY.
>> ABOUT 20 OF, QUARTER TO 5:00.
>> DO YOU HAVE AN AGE RANGE?
>> I DO NOT.
I DO NOT.
ONE THING I WOULD LIKE TO SAY IS
THAT WE HAVE BEEN MEETING WITH
ALL OF THE FAMILY MEMBERS, IT IS
A VERY, VERY DIFFICULT SCENE FOR
THE FAMILY MEMBERS, FOR ALL THE
RESPONDING, FIRST RESPONDERS, IT
IS A TRAGEDY.
IT IS A TRAGIC SCENE.
I WOULD -- WE HAVE BEEN ASKED BY
THE FAMILY MEMBERS TO ASK THE
MEMBERS OF THE PRESS TO RESPECT
THEIR PRIVACY, AND TO PLEASE
LEAVE THEM ALONE AT THIS TIME.
THEY'RE GOING THROUGH A
TREMENDOUS AMOUNT OF GRIEF WHICH
I'M SURE YOU CAN APPRECIATE.
I WOULD -- I'VE BEEN ASKED TO
ASK YOU THAT, PERSONALLY, BY THE
FAMILY MEMBERS.
ALL RIGHT?
I'LL BE BACK IN 60 MINUTES WITH
THE LIEUTENANT AND WE'LL ANSWER
ANY ADDITIONAL QUESTIONS WE CAN.
I DON'T KNOW.
>> THE POLICE CHIEF IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, UPDATING US, GIVING
US THE LATEST INFORMATION, THE
LATEST NUMBERS AND THESE ARE
AWFUL, AWFUL NUMBERS, 26 PEOPLE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
HE SAID ONE OTHER INDIVIDUAL WAS
KILLED AT A DIFFERENT LOCATION.
WE SUSPECT THAT IS THE LOCATION
OF HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY, WHERE
THE BROTHER OF THIS SUSPECTED
SHOOTER, RYAN LANZA, HAS BEEN
FOUND, SO ALTOGETHER 27 ON THE
SCENE, 26 THERE, PLUS THE
SHOOTER.
ANOTHER PERSON WILL BE 28 DEAD
PEOPLE AS A RESULT OF WHAT HAS
HAPPENED.
20 OF THOSE 26 WHO WERE KILLED,
CHILDREN, ACCORDING TO THE
POLICE CHIEF THERE IN
CONNECTICUT.
WE ALSO HEARD FROM DANNEL
MALLOY, THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT, EARLIER FROM THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
WHO HELD BACK TEARS AS HE SPOKE,
NOT ONLY AS THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES, BUT AS A PARENT,
AS A FATHER OF TWO GIRLS
HIMSELF, HE APPRECIATES AS SO
MANY MILLIONS OF PEOPLE DO THE
TRAGEDY, THE ENORMITY OF WHAT
HAS HAPPENED.
DR. DREW PINSKY HAS BEEN
LISTENING AND WATCHING.
DR. DREW, WHAT CAN WE SAY?
I DON'T THINK THERE IS ANYTHING
WE CAN SAY THAT CAN CONSOLE THE
PARENTS WHO HAVE LOST A FIRST
GRADER OR SECOND-GRADER OR
THIRD-GRADER.
20 CHILDREN WERE KILLED, ANOTHER
SIX ADULTS INCLUDING A TEACHER,
ONE OF THOSE TEACHERS BEING THE
MOTHER OF THIS SUSPECTED
SHOOTER.
>> YEAH, WHEN YOU SAY IT, WOLF,
IT JUST TAKES YOUR BREATH AWAY.
I FEEL -- I'M AFRAID I'LL LOSE
MY LUNCH THINKING ABOUT HOW
AWFUL IT WOULD JUST BE TO BE ONE
OF THOSE PARENTS.
THERE IS NOTHING THAT CAN BE
DONE FROM HERE TO HELP THOSE
PEOPLE OTHER THAN TO SAY OUR
PRAYERS AND TO KEEP THEM IN OUR
THOUGHTS.
IT IS THE PEOPLE CLOSE TO THEM
THAT ARE GOING TO GET THEM
THROUGH THIS.
NOT US.
BUT EACH OF US HAS BEEN AFFECTED
BY THIS EXPERIENCE.
FRANKLY, WOLF, I'M SORRY, I'M
STILL DISAPPOINTED BY OUR
LEADERS.
I GENUINELY APPRECIATE PRESIDENT
OBAMA'S DISPLAY OF EMOTION, THAT
WAS A VERY BIG STEP FORWARD.
BUT THEY -- THEY HAVE TO DO WHAT
EACH OF US, WHAT I WILL HAVE TO
DO AS A HEAD OF A HOUSEHOLD
TONIGHT IN MY FAMILY, WE NEED
THAT FROM OUR LEADERS, TODAY,
THAT THINGS ARE GOING TO BE
OKAY, THAT WE ARE GOING TO GET
ALONG, THAT WE ARE GOING TO
MODEL HEALTHY BEHAVIOR GOING
FORWARD, AND THAT THIS HAS --
THIS WILL STOP.
WE HAVE HAD A YEAR OF
UNCONSCIONABLE VIOLENCE THAT IS
ENDING IN A VIOLENT EPISODE
THAT, IN MY OPINION, PUTS US IN
A NEW PLACE.
CLOSE RANGE VIOLENCE AGAINST
CHILDREN.
SOMEBODY WILLFULLY, IN A
GOAL-DIRECTED FASHION, THOUGHT
THIS WAS AN OKAY BEHAVIOR.
IT IS OKAY TO PUSH SOMEONE ON A
SUB
WE MUST REQUIRE PEOPLE TO GET
HELP IF THEY HAVE ANY TENDENCY
TOWARDS VIOLENCE OR TO BE
DISCONNECTED FROM REALITY.
THERE IS SUCH A THING AS HEALTHY
AND NOT HEALTHY.
YOU KNOW, WOLF, I WAS EXPLAINING
TO SOMEBODY EARLIER THAT THESE
DAYS NO ONE WOULD ALLOW SOMEONE
IN THE WORKPLACE OR AT SCHOOL IF
THEY WERE HAVING CHEST PAIN AND
SHORTNESS OF BREATH OR HAD AN
INFECTIOUS ILLNESS.
THEY WOULD HAVE TO TAKE CARE OF
THEIR MEDICAL CONDITION.
GET A LETTER FROM A DOCTOR IN
ORDER TO COME BACK.
WE NEED THE SAME SORT OF
ATTENTION TO OUR MENTAL HEALTH
AND WE NEED TO EACH OF US
REDOUBLE OUR EFFORTS TO HAVE
HEALTHY FAMILIES TO WHICH WE ARE
COMMITTED AND THEN AGAIN ON A
MACRO LEVEL, WE NEED OUR LEADERS
TO SHOW US THE WAY.
SHOW US THE WAY TO A HEALTHIER
FUTURE WHERE THIS KIND OF THING
IS NOT OKAY AND NOT
CONTEMPLATED.
>> BECAUSE WHAT WE SEE -- SEE
THESE HORRIFIC CRIMES UNFOLDING,
WHETHER AT THE MOVIE THEATER OR
HERE, IMMEDIATELY LAW
ENFORCEMENT OVER THE YEARS HAS
ALWAYS SAID TO BE CAREFUL OF
COPY CATS.
HOW BIG OF A PROBLEM DO YOU, DR.
DREW, THINK COPY-CATS ARE IN
THESE KINDS OF MASS KILLINGS?
>> WOLF, I AM SORRY TO SAY I
THINK IT IS A MAJOR ISSUE.
AND IT'S A MAJOR ISSUE TODAY
ESPECIALLY.
I WAS RIDING ON AN ELEVATOR
YESTERDAY NIGHT HERE IN CNN LOS
ANGELES WITH A SECURITY GUARD
WHO LOOKED AT ME AND SAID, YOU
KNOW, IN A VERY SORT OF, YOU
KNOW, SORROWFUL VOICE, THERE'S
GOING TO BE COPY-CATS.
I LOOKED AT HIM.
IT WAS A GUARD I DIDN'T KNOW.
AND I SAID REALLY, ARE WE THERE?
THAT'S HOW BAD WE'VE GOTTEN?
NOT ONLY WAS HE RIGHT, HE WAS
RIGHT AND WE'VE CROSSED OVER
WITH A COPY-CAT INTO SOMETHING
TRULY EVIL, SOMETHING
UNIMAGINABLE, WHERE CHILDREN ARE
KILLED AT CLOSE RANGE.
I CAN'T EVEN SAY THE WORDS.
THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES IS BROUGHT TO TEARS BY
THIS.
ALL OF US ARE BROUGHT TO TEARS
BY IT.
EACH OF US HAS TO PAY ATTENTION
TODAY, PAY ATTENTION TO OUR
FAMILIES, PAY ATTENTION TO OUR
COMMUNITIES AND START TO SAY NO
MORE OF THIS.
WE HAVE TO FOCUS ON OUR HEALTH.
IF SOMEBODY IS AWARE OF SOMEONE
RIGHT NOW WHO'S STRUGGLING, DO
NOT BE AFRAID TO ENLIST THE HELP
OF LAW ENFORCEMENT OR MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS.
THEY ARE NOT THERE TO BE
PUNITIVE, THEY ARE THERE TO
HELP.
PEOPLE IN AUTHORITY ARE THERE TO
YOU NEED -- THEY ARE YOUR
FRIEND.
YOU NEED TO USE THEM.
DO NOT LET THIS HAPPEN IN YOUR
COMMUNITY.
>> AND, DR. DREW, AS WE TAKE A
LOOK AT WHAT YOU SAY THERE ARE
SIGNS, IN THIS SHOOTER'S LIFE
WHAT YOU'RE SUGGESTING IS IN
RECENT MONTHS OR YEARS THERE MAY
HAVE BEEN SIGNS OF EVIL INTENT
THAT WERE OBVIOUS TO PEOPLE WHO
KNEW HIM, MAYBE CLOSE FAMILY
MEMBERS AND OTHERS, AND THIS
COULD HAVE BEEN PREVENTED IF
FOLKS WOULD HAVE DONE SOMETHING,
IS THAT WHAT YOU'RE SUGGESTING?
>> I'M SUSPICIOUS OF THAT.
OF COURSE I DON'T KNOW THIS
CASE.
AGAIN, AS I SAID, WOLF, I SPENT
A LOT OF TIME IN THE MEDIA
TRYING TO HELP PEOPLE.
IT'S IMPORTANT TO MAKE SENSE OF
ALL THESE THINGS.
PART OF LEADING US OUT IS TO SAY
WHAT HAPPENED, HOW DO WE MAKE
SENSE OF THIS.
THAT'S GOOD LEADERSHIP.
SO WE'RE TRYING TO UNDERSTAND
THIS TODAY AS QUICKLY AS WE CAN.
I HAVE NO DIRECT KNOWLEDGE, BUT
MY SUSPICION IS THIS IS SOMEBODY
WHO HAS BEEN STRUGGLING FOR A
WHILE AND FOR WHOM PROBABLY
THERE WAS A CERTAIN AMOUNT OF
DENIAL ON BEHALF OF HIS PARENTS
OR FAMILY OR EVEN HIS COMMUNITY
AND THAT THESE PEOPLE WHO HAVE
HISTORIES OF LACK OF EMPATHY FOR
OTHERS, AGGRESSION, CRIMINALITY
OF ANY TYPE, THEY NEED TO BE
ADDRESSED IN A COHESIVE,
THOROUGH AND A MANNER WITHOUT
DENIAL.
YOU DON'T PRETEND THAT THINGS
ARE DIFFERENT THAN YOU WISH THEY
WERE.
YOU REALLY GO AFTER THESE
THINGS, BECAUSE IF YOU DON'T,
HORRIBLE THINGS CAN HAPPEN.
>> WE HAVE THE PICTURE NOW OF
THE PRINCIPAL OF THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL THAT WE WANT
TO SHOW OUR VIEWERS.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI IS ON THE SCENE
FOR US AS WELL.
SUSAN, A HEART-BREAKING,
HEART-WRENCHING STORY UNFOLDING.
WHAT A TRAGEDY.
THERE SHE IS, THE PRINCIPAL AT
THIS SCHOOL, DAWN HOCHSPRUNG WAS
KILLED, SHE WAS ALSO A
PSYCHOLOGIST AT THIS SMALL
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, KINDERGARTEN
THROUGH FOURTH GRADE.
AS THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES SAID, 5-YEAR-OLD TO
10-YEAR-OLD CHILDREN.
20 OF THEM KILLED NOW ACCORDING
TO THE POLICE CHIEF IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
26 PEOPLE KILLED ALTOGETHER PLUS
THE SHOOTER, THAT MAKES 27.
AND ANOTHER PERSON AT A
DIFFERENT -- AT A DIFFERENT
LOCATION.
WE EXPECT IN HOBOKEN, NEW
JERSEY.
I WANT TO SHOW OUR VIEWERS SOME
OF THE IMAGES OF WHAT HAS
HAPPENED.
>> CAR AFTER CAR AFTER CAR, SOME
OF THEM WERE FLYING UP PAST MY
HOUSE AND COMING BACK AROUND
AGAIN AND GOING TO THE SCHOOL.
THIS HOUSE IS THREE HOUSES AWAY
FROM THE SCHOOL.
>> WHEN WE FIRST ARRIVED THERE,
THERE WAS NOT A LOT OF SECURITY
TO GUARD AND THERE WERE THREE
CHILDREN THAT CAME OUT.
ONE OF THEM WAS -- HAD A VERY
BLOODY FACE.
>> WE IMMEDIATELY JUMPED IN THE
CAR AND HEADED DOWN HERE, SO
THIS IS TROUBLING.
IT WAS REALLY KIND OF MAY HEM IN
THE ROOM WITH THE KIDS AND THE
TEACHERS, TRYING TO IDENTIFY
YOUR KID, MAKING SURE THEY WERE
SAFE, FIND OUT WHAT THE
SITUATION WAS.
IT STARTED WITH THE NEIGHBORS
AND THE REST OF THEIR FRIENDS AT
SCHOOL AND THAT SORT OF THING.
>> WHAT DID YOUR DAUGHTER SAY TO
YOU?
>> THEY WERE IMMEDIATELY CRYING.
PETRIFIED OF WHAT HAPPENED AND
WHAT DID IT MEAN.
THEY'RE BOTH OLDER THAN SOME OF
THE OTHER KIDS IN THE SCHOOL, SO
UNDERSTANDING WHAT HAPPENED.
MY SON WAS IN THE GYM WHEN IT
HAPPENED, SO I THINK THAT HE
HEARD THE GUNSHOTS.
>> WE SAW POLICE OFFICERS AND WE
HEARD THEM ON THE ROOF AND IN
OUR BUILDING.
>> DID YOU HEAR ANY GUNSHOTS OR
ANYTHING LIKE THAT?
>> WELL, POLICE OFFICERS, LIKE
THEY WERE KIND OF -- THERE WERE
POLICE OFFICERS RIGHT OUT THE
DOOR TRYING TO FIND THE GUY.
>> IT WAS SHOCKING.
I GOT THE CALL AT WORK THIS
MORNING AND I CAN'T BELIEVE A
SMALL TOWN LIKE THIS WOULD EVER
HAVE ANYTHING LIKE THIS HAPPEN.
AND TO BE IN AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, THAT'S UNHEARD OF.
>> IT DOESN'T EVEN SEEM REAL.
IT JUST DOES NOT SEEM LIKE IT'S
EVEN POSSIBLE.
IT'S LIKE YOU READ IT IN THE
PAPER OR SEE IT IN THE NEWS.
YOU'RE LIKE OH, MY GOD, THAT
POOR FAMILY.
AND THEN YOU HAVE SOMETHING
HAPPEN SO CLOSE TO HOME, IT'S
LIKE I THINK I'M STILL IN SHOCK.
>> I CAN TELL YOU THAT, FIRST OF
ALL, OBVIOUSLY OUR HEARTS AND
PRAYERS GO OUT TO THE VICTIMS OF
THIS TERRIBLE INCIDENT, VERY
TRAGIC.
OUR POLICE ARE CURRENTLY WORKING
CLOSELY WITH THE NEWTOWN POLICE
DEPARTMENT.
WE HAVE MUTUAL AID AGREEMENTS IN
PLACE THAT ALLOW US TO PROVIDE
ASSETS THEY MAY NOT HAVE, ALONG
WITH THE STATE POLICE WHO HAVE
TAKEN THE LEAD IN THIS
INVESTIGATION.
>> IT'S TERRIFYING.
I'M STILL TERRIFIED.
I THINK I'M STILL IN SHOCK ABOUT
IT ALL.
>> WAS EVERYBODY CRYING, SCARED,
WANTING THEIR PARENTS TO COME
GET THEM?
>> YEAH, THEY WERE.
AND SOME PEOPLE WERE EVEN
LIKE -- THEY GOT A STOMACH ACHE.
>> THEY WOULDN'T EVEN LET US IN
THE BUILDING.
ALL I CAN SAY IS ONE OF THE COPS
SAID IT'S THE WORST THING HE'D
EVER SEEN IN HIS ENTIRE CAREER,
BUT IT WAS WHEN THEY TOLD THE
PARENTS.
ALL THESE PARENTS WERE WAITING
FOR THEIR CHILDREN TO COME OUT.
THEY THOUGHT THAT THEY WERE
STILL ALIVE.
THERE'S 20 PARENTS THAT WERE
JUST TOLD THAT THEIR CHILDREN
ARE DEAD.
IT WAS AWFUL.
>>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
>> WHEN WE FIRST ARRIVED THERE,
THERE WAS NOT A LOT OF SECURITY
TO GUARD, AND THERE WERE THREE
CHILDREN THAT CAME OUT.
ONE OF THEM WAS -- HAD A VERY
BLOODY FACE.
IT WAS A VERY VIOLENT SCENE.
THERE WERE TWO OTHER ONES THAT
THEY WERE, YOU KNOW, THEY WERE
IN THE ARMS OF A STATE TROOPER.
THEY DID NOT MOVE.
THEIR FACE WAS VERY PALE.
IT WAS VERY TRAGIC.
>> TERROR AT AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN CONNECTICUT.
A GUNMAN OPENS FIRE.
20 CHILDREN, SIX ADULTS DEAD.
THE SHOOTER DEAD AS WELL.
I WANT TO WELCOME OUR VIEWERS IN
THE UNITED STATES AND AROUND THE
WORLD.
I'M WOLF BLITZER IN THE
SITUATION ROOM.
WE'RE CONTINUING THE BREAKING
NEWS COVERAGE OF A HORRIFIC
STORY HERE IN THE UNITED STATES.
LET'S BRING IN OUR NATIONAL
CORRESPONDENT, SUSAN CANDIOTTI.
SHE'S ON THE SCENE.
SUSAN, UPDATE OUR VIEWERS WHAT
WE KNOW RIGHT NOW.
WHAT HAPPENED AROUND 9:30 A.M.
EASTERN THIS MORNING AT THAT
SMALL ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> Reporter: IT'S A SCHOOL,
WOLF, THAT HAS THE GRADES
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH THE FOURTH
GRADE.
A PLACE THAT IS SUPPOSED TO BE
FOR LEARNING AND FOR FUN FOR
THESE YOUNG CHILDREN ENDED