HONESTLY FEEL COMFORTABLE TO
TELL THEIR PRINCIPAL OF THINGS
THAT ARE GOING ON AT HOME WITH
DOMESTIC SITUATIONS THAT COULD
SPILL OVER INTO OUR SCHOOLS.
MAKING SURE THAT YOU'RE DOING
BASIC TRAINING SO THAT TEACHERS
AND STAFF GREET AND CHALLENGE,
REPORT STRANGERS, KEEP PEOPLE
OUTSIDE OF SCHOOLS.
WE HAVE MANY CRISIS PLANS IN
MOST SCHOOLS.
THE PROBLEM IS THEY'RE OFTEN
SITTING 0EN A SHELF COLLECTING
DUST.
THE STAFF HAVEN'T BEEN TRAINED
AND THEY DON'T DRILL.
WE HEARD IN CONNECTICUT
YESTERDAY THAT THE STAFF HAD
BEEN TRAINED.
WE SAW THAT STAFF KNEW WHAT TO
DO AND LITERALLY TEACHERS,
ADULTS WHO LOVE KIDS STEPPED IN
FRONT AND TOOK A BULLET TO
PROTECT THEIR CHILDREN.
I THINK THAT THE HUMAN ASPECT OF
SCHOOL SAFETY IS MUCH MORE
STRONGER THAN ANY CAMERA AND
METAL DETECTOR WILL EVER BE.
>> AND THANK YOU SO MUCH.
WE APPRECIATE THAT.
OBVIOUSLY, SO MANY OF THOSE
TEACHERS DID SUCH A HEROIC JOB
JUST GETTING THEIR CHILDREN IN
SAFE PLAYS PUTTING THEM IN
CLOSETS, LOCKING THEM IN
BATHROOMS, BARRICADING THEM
UNTIL THEY KNEW THAT THE SCHOOL
WAS SAFE, WAS IN LOCK DOWN,
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR JOINING
US.
AS THE CONNECTICUT COMMUNITY AND
THE NATION TRY TO COME TO GRIPS
WITH THIS TERRIBLE TRAGEDY,
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE A LOT OF THE
LATEST DEVELOPMENTS IN THE NEXT
HOUR OF OUR SPECIAL COVERAGE.
LIVE FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
THANK YOU.
HOW THEY'LL LIVE TOMO.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
>>> GOOD AFTERNOON, EVERYONE.
I'M DON LEMON.
YOU'RE WATCHING LIVE SPECIAL
COVERAGE FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THE SCENE OF THAT HORRIFIC
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL RAMPAGE.
>>.LIVE AT THE CNN CENTER IN
ATLANTA FOR ALL OF YOU.
I'LL BE BACK IN A FEW MINUTES
WITH THE LATEST WE KNOW ABOUT
THE VICTIMS OF THIS TRAGEDY.
FIRST WE GO TO DON IN NEWTOWN.
DON?
>> DEB, THANK YOU.
WE'LL GET BACK TO DEB IN A
MINUTE.
I WANT TO TELL VIEWERS WHERE WE
ARE RIGHT NOW.
AT THE NEWTOWN METHODIST CHURCH
JUST IN FRONT OF ME.
THIS IS CHURCHILL ROAD THAT
YOU'RE LOOKING AT HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
JUST BEYOND THAT SATELLITE TRUCK
YOU SEE DOWN THERE IS A ROAD
THAT LEADS TO THE SCHOOL AND
IT'S BEING BLOCKED OFF BY POLICE
AS YOU CAN SEE.
THE PEOPLE HERE, IT IS
UNBELIEVABLE TO WATCH THEIR
FACES AND TO COME INTO TOWN
TODAY AND SEE -- YOU CAN SEE THE
PAIN.
IT IS VISIBLE ON THEIR FACES AND
IT IS PALPABLE HERE.
AND OVER THE NEXT HOUR, AS LONG
AS I'M ON THE AIR HERE, WE'RE
GOING TO BE AS RESPECTFUL AS WE
CAN ABOUT TELLING YOU THE STORY
AND MANY THINGS WE'RE GOING TO
LEARN ALONG WITH YOU AND SO BEAR
WITH US.
WE MAY NOT GET IT ALL RIGHT, BUT
WE ARE HERE TO INFORM YOU BUT TO
BE RESPECTFUL OF THE VICTIMS AND
THE PEOPLE DEALING WITH SUCH A
HORRIFIC TRAGEDY.
I'D LIKE TO WELCOME OUR VIEWERS
HERE IN THE UNITED STATES AND
AROUND THE WORLD.
THIS IS UNSPEAKABLE WHAT
HAPPENED IN THIS TOWN YESTERDAY.
20 CHILDREN MASSACRED ALONG WITH
SIX ADULTS AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
POLICE SAY THE SHOOTER AND WE'LL
SAY HIS NAME ONCE IN THIS
BROADCAST AND WE HOPE THAT IS
THE ONLY TIME AND THAT IS JUST
FOR THE RECORD OF JOURNALISM,
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA AND THAT
HE KILLED HIMSELF AFTER THAT
RAMPAGE.
TODAY, THE COLLECTIVE HEART OF A
NATION AND THE WORLD REALLY
HEAVY OVER THIS.
WE GRIEVE FOR THE FAMILIES.
AND WE GRIEVE AT THE IDEA THAT
SOMEONE COULD BE CAPABLE OF SUCH
A TERRIBLE ACT.
THOSE WHO LIVED THROUGH THE
MASSACRE FIND IT REALLY HARD TO
DESCRIBE.
>> IT WAS A LOT OF -- A LOT OF
REALLY SCARED PARENTS LOOKING
FOR THEIR KIDS, A LOT OF
GRATEFUL PEOPLE AND YOU KNOW,
NEIGHBORS AND FRIENDS AND -- IT
WAS -- IT WAS SURREAL.
I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW HOW TO DESCRIBE IT.
>> LET ME TELL YOU EVERYTHING
THAT WE KNOW AT THIS HOUR RIGHT
NOW.
AS NEWTOWN MOURNS, POLICE SAY
THEY HAVE IDENTIFIED ALL 20
CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTED KILLED
AT THE SCHOOL.
THEY TOLD US THAT THE SHOOTER
FORCED HIS WAY INTO THE SCHOOL.
AND WE JUST GOT THIS PICTURE OF
HIM FROM OUR AFFILIATE WFSB.
AND WE JUST FOUND OUT FROM A LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIAL WERE THAT
THE SUSPECT HAD SOME SORT OF
ALTERCATION WITH PEOPLE AT THE
SCHOOL JUST A FEW DAYS BEFORE
THE KILLINGS.
POLICE SAY THE SUSPECT FIRST
SHOT AND KILLED HIS MOTHER,
NANCY, AT HER HOME BEFORE
DRIVING TO THE SCHOOL AND THEN
OPENING FIRE.
AUTHORITIES TELL US THAT THEY'RE
MAKING GOOD PROGRESS IN
DETERMINING WHY THIS HORRIFIC
CRIME HAPPENED.
>> OUR INVESTIGATORS AT THE
CRIME SCENE, THE SCHOOL AND
SECONDARILY AT THE SECONDARY
CRIME SCENE THAT WE DISCUSSED
WHERE THE FEMALE WAS LOCATED
DECEASED DID PRODUCE SOME
VERY -- A VERY GOOD EVIDENCE IN
THIS INVESTIGATION THAT OUR
INVESTIGATORS WILL BE ABLE TO
USE AND HOPEFULLY PAINTING THE
COMPLETE PICTURE AS TO HOW AND
MORE IMPORTANTLY WHY THIS
OCCURRED.
>> SO TELL YOU RIGHT NOW, POLICE
ARE ALSO SAYING THAT ALL THREE
GUNS, NOT TWO, WERE RECOVERED
FROM THE SHOOTER'S BODY IN THE
SCHOOL.
A GLOCK, A SIX SAUER, AND A
BUSHMASTER WERE OWNED BY HIS
MOTHER.
INVESTIGATORS SAY THEY KNOW
WHICH ONE HE USED TO KILL
HIMSELF BUT THEY WON'T REVEAL
THAT INFORMATION.
ALL OF THIS HAS LEFT US WITH
MORE QUESTIONS REALLY THAN
ANSWERS AND SOME QUESTIONS WE
MAY NEVER GET ANSWERS TO ABOUT
THE POSSIBLE MOTIVE OF THIS
SHOOTER.
CNN'S MARY SNOW HAS A CLOSER
LOOK AT THE SUSPECT FOR US NOW.
>> SHORTLY AFTER THE HORRIFIC
SHOOTINGS, POLICE AND S.W.A.T.
TEAMS DESCENDED ON THE LANZA
HOME BEHIND ME AND IT'S CLOSED
OFF BY POLICE.
INVESTIGATORS ARE NOW SUGGESTING
THAT THEY ARE PIECING TOGETHER
INFORMATION LEADING TO POSSIBLE
ANSWERS ABOUT HOW AND DWLP
HAPPENED.
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE OF THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE SAYING
THAT IN HIS WORDS, GOOD EVIDENCE
IS BEING RECOVERED BUT HE DID
NOT GO INTO DETAIL.
IN TERMS OF THE WEAPONS USED, WE
DO KNOW THAT THREE WEAPONS WERE
RECOVERED AT THE SCENE OF THE
SHOOTING NEAR THE SUSPECT'S
BODY.
THERE WERE TWO HANDGUNS AND A
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE.
CNN HAS BEEN REPORTING THAT
THOSE GUNSES WERE PURCHASED BY
HIS MOTHER, NANCY LANZA.
THERE'S NOT MUCH WE DO KNOW
ABOUT NANCY LANZA.
WE SPOKE TO A NEIGHBOR EARLIER
IN THE DAY, AND SHE SAID THAT
SHE KNEW HER.
BUT THERE WAS NOTHING OUT OF THE
ORDINARY THAT SHE COULD SEE.
>> SHE WAS LIKE A NORMAL ANYBODY
ELSE IN THIS NEIGHBORHOOD.
YOU KNOW, DECORATE THE HOUSE AND
THE HOUSE WAS ALWAYS, YOU KNOW,
PRISTINE AND I MEAN, SHE WAS
JUST LIKE ANY OTHER HOUSEWIFE.
>> AS FOR ADAM LANZA, FORMER
CLASSMATES DESCRIBE HIM AS BEING
A SMART STUDENT, SOMEONE WHO WAS
QUIET.
KEPT TO HIMSELF.
A NEIGHBOR WHO KNEW HIM IN
RECENT YEARS DESCRIBED HIM AS
TROUBLED.
MARY SNOW, CNN, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> ALL RIGHT, MARY, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
I WANT TO BRINGING IN DEB
FEYERICK.
DEB, OF COURSE, IS IN ATLANTA
LEADING OUR COVERAGE FROM THERE
ALONG WITH NICK WHO HAS BEEN
GETTING INFORMATION ON THE
VICTIMS, DEB.
>> WHAT'S INTERESTING IS WE'RE
SLOWLY LEARNING SOME OF THE
NAMES OF THE VICTIMS, MOSTLY THE
ADULTS OF THIS ATTACK.
THERE WERE 208 CHILDREN BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10.
SO YOUNG.
THEY DIED IN THE SHOOTING SPREE
ALONG WITH THOSE SIX ADULTS,
MANY OF THEM EDUCATORS IN THE
SCHOOL.
THE SCHOOL'S PRINCIPAL WAS ONE
OF THOSE.
ALSO THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST.
THOSE TWOS WOMEN RAN TOWARDS THE
DOOR WHEN THEY HEARD THE GUNFIRE
TO SEE WHAT WAS GOING ON TO SEE
WHETHER THEY COULD HAVE
PREVENTED THIS TRAGEDY THAT
UNFOLDED.
NICK VALENCIA HERE IN ATLANTA,
YOU'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT WHO
THEY WERE.
NICK,ING WHAT DO YOU HAVE SO
FAR?
>> GOOD AFTERNOON, DEB.
IT'S BEEN AN EXHAUSTING DAY,
MORNING AND AFTERNOON AS WE GOOE
BEGIN TO PIECE TOGETHER THE
DETAILS OF EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED
YESTERDAY MORNING IN NEWTOWN,
THE SITE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WHAT WE DO KNOW IS 26 PEOPLE ARE
DEAD.
TWO NAMES CNN HAS BEEN ABLE TO
INDEPENDENTLY CONFIRM TWO OF
THOSE, ONE BEING DOWN
HOCHSPRUNG.
SHE BEGAN AS THE PRINCIPAL
AROUND TWO YEARS AGO BEING
DESCRIBED AS A SERIOUS BUT
AFFABLE LEADER, A TOUGH LEADER
IN THE RIGHT SORT OF SENSE,
SOMEBODY THAT YOU WOULD WANT
EDUCATING YOUR KIDS.
SHE RECENTLY OVERSAW IS THE
SCHOOL SECURITY SYSTEM PROJECT.
EVERY VISITOR WAS REQUIRED TO
BUZZ IN THAT FRONT ENTRANCE
BEFORE ENTERING.
WE DO KNOW NOW AS DETAILS
UNFOLDED ABOUT THE SUSPECTED
SHOOTER THAT HE FORCED HIS WAY
INTO THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AS
DON LEMON WAS REPORTING.
GETTING BACK TO THE PRINCIPAL
HOCHSPRUNG, SHE WAS AN EXTREMELY
PASSIONATE PERSON, PASSIONATE
ABOUT EDUCATION.
SHE HAD ABOUT 1 YEARS OF
ADMINISTRATIVE EXPERIENCE BEFORE
COMING TO SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
SHE BELIEVES BEHIND A HUSBAND,
TWO DAUGHTERS AND THREE STEP
DAUGHTERS.
ALSO AMONG THE VICTIMS IS MARY
SHERLACH.
SHE WAS A SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST,
AS YOU MENTIONED, DEB, AND DEB,
MARY SHERLACH AND HOW MUCH
SBRUNG BOTH IN AN ADMINISTRATIVE
MEETING.
WE LEARNED FROM ONE PARENT WHO
TOLD CNN THEY WERE THERE WITH
THE ADVICE PRINCIPAL, THE
PRINCIPAL AND THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST WHEN THEY HEARD A
LOUD POP, POP, POP NOISE OUTSIDE
IN THE HALLWAY, AT WHICH POINT
THE PRINCIPAL AND THE
PSYCHOLOGIST WENT TO INVESTIGATE
AND CHECK OUT WHAT WAS HAPPENING
IN THEIR SCHOOL.
WE KNOW NOW THAT THE SUSPECTER
HAD BURST INTO THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AND THOSE TWO, THE
PRINCIPAL AND THE PSYCHOLOGIST
WENTZ TO CHECK IT OUT, BUT THEY
WANT DID NOT RETURN.
ALSO, AND I WANT TO BE CLEAR
ABOUT THIS, KATE BOLDUAN SPOKE
TO A FIRST GRADER IN A CLASSROOM
THAT WAS THE SITE OF THE
SHOOTING.
ONE OF THE CLASSROOMS WHERE THE
SUSPECTED SHOOTER ENTERED, AND
THAT FIRST GRADER TOLD OUR CNN'S
KATE BOLDUAN THAT HE SAW HIS
TEACHER, 27-YEAR-OLD VICTORIA
SOTO SHOT BY THE SHOOTER.
CNN HAS BEEN UNABLE TO CONFIRM
WHETHER OR NOT VICKI SOTO IS
AMONG THE VICTIMS.
THAT'S A PICTURE OF HER RIGHT
THERE, JUST 27 YEARS OLD, DEB.
SHE HAD A HANDFUL OF YEARS OF
TEACHING EXPERIENCE.
IT'S SAID THAT SHE DISTRACTED
THE GUNMAN WHILE HER SCHOOL
CHILDREN, WHILE HER STUDENTS
WERE ABLE TO RUN PAST THAT
GUNMAN.
A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE CALLING HER
A HERO.
>> WHAT'S SO INCREDIBLE, THE
POLICE HAVE NOT RELEASED ANY OF
THE NAMES OF EITHER THE CHILDREN
OR THE ADULTS YET.
WE HAVE BEEN ABLEO PICK UP
CERTAIN NAMES HERE AND THERE
BECAUSE OF PEOPLE TWEETING OUT
THEIR HORROR AND THEIR
CONDOLENCES.
THE SISTER OF VICKIE SOTO ON HER
ACCOUNT, MY SISTER DIED
PROTECTING HER STUDENTS.
GOD, WHY DID YOU TAKE HER?
ANOTHER PERSON WHO WE BELIEVE IS
A VICTIM A TWEET SAID TO ALL OF
OUR HEROES THAT WERE PART OF
THIS SENSELESS LOSS OF LIVES,
PRAYERS AND LOVE.
THIS IS SORT OF A SNAPSHOT OF
LIFE JUST TRAGICALLY INTERRUPTED
AND CUT SHORT.
NICK VALENCIA IN THE NEWSROOM,
THANKS.
GET BACK TO US AS SOON AS YOU
HAVE MORE INFORMATION ON THIS
PART OF THE STORY.
DON?
>> ALL RIGHT, THANK YOU GUYS
VERY MUCH.
I TOLD YOU THAT WE WERE HERE AT
THE NEWTOWN METHODIST CHURCH.
THIS IS BETH SQUARE.
WE'VE BEEN SEEING PEOPLE COMING
IN HERE AND WANTING TO PAY
RESPECTS AND JUST TO SORT OF
PROP UP THE PEOPLE WHO ARE HERE
AND SHOW SUPPORT.
KRISTIN AND MATT PANICHELLA FROM
THE WESTON CONNECTICUT.
>> IT'S ABOUT 20 MILES AWAY.
>> YOU'VE GOT FLOWERS IN YOUR
HAND.
WHY?
>> I THINK THE LEAST WE COULD DO
IS COME PAY RESPECT TO THE
FAMILIES AND TO THE LIVES THAT
WERE LOST HERE.
>> AS YOU THINK ABOUT IT, YOU'VE
GOT OLIVIA IS 1-YEAR-OLD.
CAN YOU IMAGINE WHAT THESE
FAMILIES ARE DEALING WITH?
>> NO, I THINK THAT'S BEEN THE
MOST HEARTBREAKING PART OF THIS
WHOLE THING IS WANTING TO BE
THERE FOR THEM AND TRYING TO
UNDER THE PAIN THEY MUST BE
GOING THROUGH.
>> YEAH.
AND THAT'S WITH A CHILD.
I DON'T HAVE A CHILD.
BUT I CAN'T IMAGINE SENDING MY
CHILD OFF TO SCHOOL.
>> THAT'S THE WORST PART.
THAT'S THE WORST PART IS JUST
PUTTING THAT BACKPACK ON YOUR
KID AND PUTTING THEM ON THE BUS
AND THEM NOT COMING HOME.
>> YOU NEVER THINK YOU'RE NEVER
GOING TO SEE THEM AGAIN.
THAT'S THE WORST PART ABOUT IT.
>> HOW IS EVERYONE AROUND HERE
DEALING WITH IT?
YOUR NEIGHBORS, ARE YOU TALKING
ABOUT IT?
DO THEY FEEL THE SAME AS YOU?
>> YEAH, MY FAMILY'S BEEN
CALLING, MY WIFE'S FAMILY BEEN
CALLING US ASKING US IF WE KNEW
ANYBODY.
I WORK RELATIVELY CLOSE IN
DANBURY.
I'M SURE I HAVEN'T HEARD YET IF
ANYBODY'S BEEN AFFECTED BY
WHAT'S HAPPENED HERE BUT I'M
SURE NEXT WEEK I'LL PROBABLY
HEAR SOMETHING.
>> YOU BARELY OPENED YOUR MOUTH
BEFORE YOU STARTED TO TEAR UP.
I CAN SEE BEHIND THE SUNGLASSES
AND YOU SEE THIS BIG LUG OF GUYS
WHO CAN BARELY GET THEIR WORDS
OUT.
>> YEAH, IT'S DIFFICULT.
ESPECIALLY BEING SO CLOSE TO
HOME.
IT MAKES IT EVEN THAT MUCH MORE
DIFFICULT.
>> YEAH.
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THE FOLKS
HERE, IF ANYTHING?
IS THERE YOU CAN SAY TO THEM?
>> I DON'T KNOW IF THERE REALLY
IS ANYTHING.
I GUESS STAY STRONG BUT IT SEEMS
SO HARD TO DO THAT RIGHT NOW.
IT'S STILL KIND OF FRESH.
>> WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE THE
COUNTRY TO KNOW OR DO TO SUPPORT
THIS COMMUNITY?
>> PRAYERS, LOTS OF PRAYERS I
THINK RIGHT NOW, ESPECIALLY THE
WEEK BEFORE CHRISTMAS AND
HANUKKAH, AND EVERYONE JUST
THOUGHT IT WAS GOING TO BE
SOMETHING DIFFERENT, I'M SURE.
>> THANK YOU, GUYS.
THANKS FOR COMING ON AND SHOWING
YOUR SUPPORT.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> IT MEANS THE WORLDED I'M SURE
TO THE FOLKS HERE.
THAT'S KRISTIN AND MATT AND
THEIR 1-YEAR-OLD OLIVIA.
THEY ARE JUST ONE AMONG MANY
PEOPLE WHO HAVE BEEN SHOWING UP
HERE TO PAY THEIR RESPECTS, AND
AS I SAID, THE CHURCH HERE, THE
METHODIST CHURCH OPEN 24 HOURS
AND THEY'VE ASKED THE MEDIA NOT
TO INTERVIEW PEOPLE.
SO IF THEY COME OUT AND THEY
WANT TO TALK LIKE THIS COUPLE
DID, THEN WE WILL TALK TO THEM.
IF YOU GO DOWN HERE TO BETH
SQUARE, THERE'S A SIGN THAT SAYS
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN.
IS THE STREET THAT LEADS UP TO
THE SCHOOL BLOCKED OFF BY
POLICE.
ANDTOM EVERY SINGLE PERSON THAT
I'VE SPOKEN TO, SAYS, YOU KNOW,
IT'S NEVER THIS BUSY HERE
ESPECIALLY ON A SATURDAY OR A
SUNDAY.
IT GETS A LITTLE BIT BUSY
BECAUSE IT IS ONE OF THE SQUARES
HERE IN THE TOWN BUT NOT THIS
BUSY.
SO PEOPLE ARE COMING HERE
BECAUSE THEY'RE SEEING IT ON
TELEVISION AND WANT TO GIVE THIS
COMMUNITY A COMMUNITY GROUP HUG,
SO TO SPEAK.
SO WE'LL CONTINUE TO TALK TO THE
PEOPLE COMING OUT HERE SO THAT
YOU CAN HEAR HOW THEY'RE GETTING
SUPPORT HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
AS I MENTIONED JUST A LITTLE BIT
EARLIER AS WE SADLY HAVE TO GO
BACK TO THIS GUNMAN, HE FORCED
HIS WAY INTO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
NO ONE LET HIM IN VOLUNTARILY.
HE FORCED HIS WAY IN.
THE SCHOOL RECENTLY INSTALLED A
NEW SECURITY SYSTEM THAT LOCKED
DOORS AT 9:30 A.M. AND VISITORS
WERE SUPPOSED TO RING A BELL AND
GET CLEARANCE FROM THE FRONT
OFFICE.
WE DON'T KNOW WHETHER THE
SHOOTER BURST INTO THE SCHOOL
AND STARTED HIS BLOODY RAMPAGE
BEFORE OR AFTER 9:00 A.M.
LOU PA LUMBO, A RETIRED NASSAU
COUNTY POLICE OFFICER IN NEW
YORK, HE NOW HEADS A SECURITY
AGENCY, LOU, WE STARTED THIS
YESTERDAY ON THE AIR.
HAD NO IDEA WHEN WE WERE
COVERING THIS BOTH OF US, I HAD
ONE LINE OF INFORMATION THAT
SAID POLICE ARE RUSHING TO THE
SCENE OF A SCHOOL FOR A POSSIBLE
SHOOTING, AND AS YOU AND I WERE
TALKING YESTERDAY MORNING, AND
NOW THIS.
ONE MORE, ANOTHER SCHOOL
TRAGEDY.
>> DON, ALMOST INDESCRIBABLE AND
DIFFICULT TO SPEAK TO.
THE REAL PROBLEM IS WHAT THIS IS
SYMPTOM I CAN OF.
THERE'S AN IMMENSE AMOUNT OF
DYSFUNCTION IN OUR COUNTRY.
WE NEED TO JUST WRAP OUR ARMS
AROUND IT, WHETHER IT'S OUR
INABILITY TO TALK ABOUT
RESPONSIBLE REGULATION HOW
PEOPLE ACQUIRE FIREARMS, WHAT WE
NEED TO DO TO SECURE OUR
SCHOOLS, OUR POLITICAL SYSTEM,
YOU KNOW, WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
GUN LEGISLATION AND ASSAULT
RIFLE BANS.
I DON'T KNOW HOW WE CAN TALK
ABOUT THESE THINGS.
YOU HAVE A REPUBLICAN-CONTROLLED
HOUSE AND I'M CERTAIN A NUMBER
OF SOUTHERN CONSERVATIVE
DEMOCRATS WHO ARE NOT GOING TO
VOTE FOR ANY GUN LAWS WITH THIS
PRESIDENT.
YOU KNOW, WE'RE IN A REAL
QUAGMIRE HERE.
YOU WOULD HOPE AT SOME POINT
SENSIBILITY WOULD OVERRIDE THIS
AND THE TWO EXTREMES ON THIS
PLATFORM COME TO THE MIDDLE TO
UNDERSTAND WE NEED TO ADDRESS
THIS PROBLEM OF THE
INAPPROPRIATE MANNER IN WHICH
PEOPLE ACQUIRE FIREARMS.
IT ISN'T JUST THROUGH PURCHASING
THEM IN A GUN STORE.
AND THESE LAST TWO INSTANCES,
BOTH IN OREGON, AND NOW IN
CONNECTICUT, WE HAD YOUNG MEN IN
OREGON BREAK INTO A HOME AND
STEAL AN ASSAULT RIFLE AND IN
THIS INSTANCE, THIS YOUNG MAN
ACQUIRED AN ASSAULT RIFLE FROM
HIS HOME.
BOTH OF THEM UNSECURED.
YOU HAVE TO SAFEGUARD THESE
WEAPONS.
THAT'S ONE PROBLEM WE'RE HAVING
HERE.
THAT'S ALL -- THERE'S NO SUCH
THING AS SINGLE CAUSALITY.
THERE ISN'T ANY MAGIC WAND OR
ANY GUN LAW THAT'S GOING TO FIX
THIS DON.
THIS IS SO DISCONCERTING.
>> LOU?
>> YES.
>> LOU, CAN WE PUT THE GUNS, A
PICTURE OF THAT GUN BACK UP.
I WANT TO TELL OF MY EXPERIENCE
HERE.
LOU, WHEN I WAS IN COLORADO,
COVERING THAT THEATER MASSACRE,
THE GUN THAT YOU SEE AT THE
BOTTOM OF THE SCREEN, IF YOU CAN
PUT IT BACK UP, THAT AR-15, YOU
SUE HE THAT?
>> THAT'S TO BE MORE ACCURATE,
THAT'S AN M-4 CARBINE, IT'S AN
M-4 CARBINE.
>> OKAY.
I WENT INTO A GUN STORE AND
PURCHASED A GUN THAT LOOKS
PRETTY MUCH LIKE THAT GUN.
WITHIN 20 MINUTES, I'M NOT A
RESIDENT OF THE STATE OF
COLORADO.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THEY DID WITH
THE BACKGROUND CHECK.
THEY LOOKED AT MY DRIVER'S
LICENSE.
I HANDED THEM $800.
AND WALKED OUT OF THE STORE WITH
A GUN THAT LOOKS LIKE THAT GUN
AND AMMUNITION AND TO THIS DAY,
IT'S SITTING IN THE CNN SECURITY
OFFICE, BUT STILL, HOW CAN
SOMEONE JUST WALK INTO A STORE
AND 20 MINUTES LATER WALK OUT
WITH AN ASSAULT RIFLE?
HOW DOES THAT HAPPEN IN THIS
COUNTRY?
>> WE HAVE A FAILED SYSTEM, DON.
I'VE HAD THIS CONVERSATION WITH
NUMEROUS CORRESPONDENTS AND
JOURNALISTS, SOME OF THEM WITH
CNN.
THE PROBLEM SIMPLY STATED IS
THAT WITH HANDGUNS, FOR EXAMPLE,
IF YOU HAVE NO CRIMINAL HISTORY,
WE'RE PREPARED TO SURRENDER ONE
TO YOU ON A DRIVER'S LICENSE.
IN LAW ENFORCEMENT, BEFORE WE
ARM OUR POLICE, WE VET THEM A
BIT DIFFERENTLY.
YOU HAVE TO GO THROUGH CRIMINAL
HISTORY CHECK.
PSYCHOLOGICAL PROFILING WHERE WE
PUT YOU THROUGH A MINNESOTA
MULTIFACIC SCREENING, RORSCHACH,
WORD ASSOCIATION AND INTERVIEWS
WITH PSYCHOLOGISTS AND
PSYCHIATRISTS.
THEN EXTENSIVE FIREARMS TRAINING
AND IN ADDITION CLASSROOM
TRAINING EXPLAINING TO YOU USE
OF FORCE.
DEADLY PHYSICAL FORCE IN
PARTICULAR.
THE FACT THAT YOU'RE CAPABLE OF
WALKING INTO CERTAIN STATES IN
THIS COUNTRY AND BUYING WEAPONS
OF THIS TYPE WITHOUT US KNOWING
ANYTHING ABOUT YOU IS
REPREHENSIBLE AND IT'S ONE OF
THE PROBLEMS THAT NEEDS TO BE
ADDRESSED.
IT DOESN'T HAVE TO GO IN THE
FORMAT OF A GUN LAW.
YOU KNOW, MY POSITION ON THIS
WHOLE TOPIC AT THIS POINT IS IT
SEEMS TO BE WRAPPED AROUND A
CONSTITUTIONAL RIGHT TO SECOND
AMENDMENT.
I'D LOVE TO SEE THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT COME IN AND REQUIRE
PROPER VETTING OF PEOPLE THAT
WOULD LIKE HANDGUNS OR IF YOU
REALLY FEEL THIS NEED ASSAULT
RIFLES SO WE KNOW SOMETHING
ABOUT YOU, LITTLE MORE THAN THE
FACT YOU'VE NEVER BEEN ARRESTED.
AND THEN WE GO THROUGH THE
EDUCATIONAL PROCESS OF
IMPRESSING UPON YOU THE
IMPORTANCE OF SAFEGUARDING THESE
WEAPONS.
THIS IS A BIG PROBLEM.
BUT IT CAN BE ADDRESSED.
THE UNFORTUNATE PART, DON, IT'S
A POLITICAL ISSUE AND IT
SHOULDN'T BE.
WE'RE SUFFERING THE
CONSEQUENCES.
>> IT'S NOT AND IT SHOULDN'T BE.
IT HAS NOTHING TO DO WITH LEFT
OR RIGHT.
AND THAT'S WHAT PEOPLE DON'T
GET.
IF YOU EVEN TALKING ABOUT THIS
NOW PEOPLE ON SOCIAL MEDIA ARE
SAYING YOU'RE SUCH A LEFTY
LIBERAL.
I'M NOT.
IT HAS NOTHING TO DO WITH THAT.
IT IS A COMMON SENSE ISSUE.
LISTEN IN, THAT CONVERSATION
WITH YOU AND THIS IS A REAL
CONVERSATION.
I WARNED THE VIEWERS BEFORE
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE A REAL
CONVERSATION HERE.
I SMOEED MY IGNORANCE ABOUT GUNS
BECAUSE I DON'T KNOW, ONE
ASSAULT RIFLE LOOKS THE SAME TO
ME.
SO SOMEONE LIKE ME, LOU, WHO HAS
NEVER TAKEN A GUN CLASS, NEVER
GONE TO A GUN RANGE EXCEPT TO DO
A STORY AND MAYBE SHOT A GUN
ONCE OR TWICE, TO BE ABLE TO GO
IN AND THE AMMUNITION AND I
COULD WALK OUT AND IF I WAS MAD
AT SOMEONE JUST GO FIRE AT
PEOPLE, I DON'T UNDERSTAND HOW
THAT HAPPENS IN A COUNTRY.
FORGIVE ME, THAT'S NOT A LEFT OR
RIGHT THING.
>> I'VE SPENT 39 YEARS IN THE
LAW ENFORCEMENT COMMUNITY AS AN
ACTIVE LAW ENFORCEMENT AGENT.
AND I'VE BEEN PROTECTING PEOPLE
FOR THE PAST 32 YEARS PRIVATELY.
A LOT OF THIS ELUDES ME, AS
WELL.
BUT WHAT REALLY ELUDES ME IS OUR
ABILITY TO SIT DOWN AND COME TO
COMMON GROUND BETWEEN THE TWO
EXTREMES THAT EXIST IN THE
COUNTRY.
ONE IS THE NRA THAT BELIEVE IF
YOU CAN SEE LIGHTNING AND HEAR
THUNDER, YOU SHOULD OWN A GUN
AND THEN THE EXTREME LEFT
LIBERALS THAT THINK WE'RE JUST
GOING TO WAVE THE MAGIC WAND AND
ERASE 300 MILLION FIREARMS THAT
WE HAVE KNOWLEDGE OF TODAY.
YOU NEED TO SIT DOWN IN THE
MIDDLE.
>> NOT GOING TO HAPPEN.
>> YOU'RE RIGHT.
THAT'S UNFORTUNATELY THE TRUTH
HERE.
THAT'S WHY IN A SENSE WE'RE
SPINNING OUR WHEELS.
THERE IS A REMEDY TO THE
PROBLEM.
PART OF IT REVOLVES AROUND OUR
ABILITY TO PROPERLY VET PEOPLE
AND CONTINUOUS EDUCATION WITH
PEOPLE AND LAW ENFORCEMENT, WE
ARE TAUGHT AND IT'S IMPRESSED
UPON US THE NEED TO SAFEGUARD
YOUR WEAPONS.
THE REST OF AMERICA IS ON A
WHOLE ANOTHER PAGE.
WE'RE ON ONE PAGE, THEY'RE ON
ANOTHER.
WE GO THROUGH ONE VETTING
PROCESS, THEY GO THROUGH
BASICALLY NONE.
THIS IS THE DISCONNECT.
>> LOU?
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO LEAVE IT
THERE.
I APPRECIATE THE CONVERSATION.
AND I KNOW HOW YOU'RE FEELING
BECAUSE I'VE MET YOUR KIDS.
AND I'VE MET YOUR WIFE AND I'M
SURE YOU UGH HADDED THEM A LOT
YESTERDAY AS WELL YOU SHOULD AND
LOU PALUMBO, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
>> THANK YOU, DON.
>>> WE KNOW A LOT OF YOU MAY
WANT TO HELP THE VICTIMS AND THE
FAMILIES AND EVERYONE GRIEVING
IN THE COMMUNITY.
GO TO OUR IMPACT YOUR WORLD P  E
PAGE@CNN.COM/IMPACT.
CNN.COM/IMPACT.
DEB, I'M GOING TO GO BACK TO YOU
IN ATLANTA.
BUT THIS IS SOMETHING THAT'S
REALLY UPSETTING TO ALL OF US,
AND I THINK THAT WE REALLY NEED
TO DISCUSS THIS.
DEB FEYERICK HAS NEW INFORMATION
ON THE ALLEGED SHOOTER'S MOTHER.
WHAT DO YOU HAVE?
>> WE ARE LOOKING INTO WHO THIS
WOMAN WAS.
NANCY LANZA.
BRAND NEW DETAILS ABOUT HER.
SHE LIKED TO GARDEN, PLAY A DICE
GAME CALLED BUNK COWITH HER
GIRLFRIENDS.
A NEIGHBOR SAYS THEY SEEMED LIKE
A NICE NORMAL FAMILY.
POLICE SAY THAT NANCY'S SON ADAM
KILLEDED HER, SHOT HER TO DEATH
IN HER NEWTOWN HOME BEFORE HE
WENT TO THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
IT'S NOT CLEAR WHY HE WAS GOING
TO THAT SCHOOL.
THAT IS ONE OF THE THINGS
DETECTIVES ARE TRYING TO
INVESTIGATE.
THERE HAD BEEN SOME REPORTS SHE
MAY HAVE BEEN A TEACHER THERE.
DAVID JOINS ME ON THE PHONE FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
YOU'VE TALKED WITH SEVERAL OF
THE NEIGHBORS.
HOW ARE THEY DESCRIBING HER?
>> WELL, DEB, YOU'RE STARTING TO
GET SORT OF AN EMERGING PICTURE
OF THIS WOMAN, THE MOTHER OF THE
SHOOTER HERE.
AND LIKE YOU MENTIONED, THIS IS
A WOMAN WHO LIVED IN AN AFFLUENT
NEIGHBORHOOD IN NEWTOWN.
YOU TRAVEL UP THE ROAD, IT'S ONE
OF THE MOST PICTURESQUE PARTS OF
THIS TOWN IN SOUTHWESTERN
CONNECTICUT, OVERLOOKS ROLLING
HILLS.
SEEMS OUT OF A ROBERT FROST
POEM, BUT IT'S THE KIND OF PLACE
WHERE NEIGHBORS PARTICULARLY ON
THIS ONE STREET SEEM VERY NIGHT
KNIT.
THOSE ARE THEIR WORDS, AND ONE
OF THE NEIGHBORS THAT I SPOKE
WITH SAID LIKE YOU MENTIONED,
THEY USED TO CONGREGATE EVERY SO
OFTEN FOR PARLOR GAMES, PLAYED
DICE.
AND THEN AT THE SAME TIME, WE'RE
HEARING THESE OTHER CONFLICTING
REPORTS HERE, THIS IDEA THAT
THIS IS A WOMAN THAT HAD
SEVERAL.
VERY HEAVY GUNS IN HER
POSSESSION.
SHE HAD TWO SONS, MOVED TO THE
AREA IN ABOUT 1998, DIVORCED
FROM HER HUSBAND AND RAISED HER
SONS THEREAFTER.
BUT THE PICTURE THAT SORT OF
EMERGES, THESE TWO SORT OF
CONFLICTING IMAGES OF THIS ONE
OF THIS WOMAN WHO IS SORT OF A
QUIET MILD MANNERED PLEASANT
WOMAN WHO IS GARDENING DURING
THE DAY AND WORKING WITH
LANDSCAPING COMPANIES IN HER
HIGH LIE AFFLUENT HOME AND
ANOTHER THAT WAS HOLDING ON TO
THESE FAIRLY HEAVY DUTY WEAPONS,
THE BUSHMASTER IS A WEAPON
THAT'S AKIN TO SOME OF THE
ASSAULT WEAPONS THAT WE'VE SEEN
IN PLACES LIKE AFGHANISTAN.
AND IT JUST -- IT'S REALLY SORT
OF A CONFUSING PAINTED PICTURE
THAT'S EMERGED HERE.
ONE OF THE NEIGHBORS THAT I
SPOKE TO SAID VERY SIMPLY,
SOMETHING DOESN'T QUITE ADD UP.
DEB?
>> AND WHAT'S INTERESTING,
DAVID, AND I WANTED TO GET TO
THAT POINT BECAUSE I READ THAT
EARLIER THAT THE NEIGHBORS SAID
SOMETHING SIMPLY DID NOT ADD UP.
DID THE NEIGHBOR EVER HEAR HER
FIRING THE GUNS?
I KNOW THE HOUSES ARE KIND OF
FAR APART.
DID THE NEIGHBOR EVER SAY THAT
NANCY LANZA HAD SOME SORT OF,
YOU KNOW, ARGUMENT WITH HER SON,
THAT SHE WAS COMPLAINING ABOUT
HIM?
BECAUSE IT APPEARS THAT THEY
WERE LIVING TOGETHER IN THAT
HOME, NO?
>> YEAH, YOU KNOW, I ASKED HER
THAT QUESTION SPECIFICALLY AND
THE ANSWER WAS CATEGORICALLY NO.
THIS IS A WOMAN THAT WAS
EFFECTIVELY -- LET'S PUT IT THIS
WAY.
THIS IS NOT SOMEONE SHE KNEW
WELL OR ANY OF THE NEIGHBORS
KNEW WELL.
LIKE ANY NEIGHBORHOOD, YOU KNOW
MAYBE ONE OR TWO HOUSES DOWN OR
THREE OR FOUR ON THE OTHER SIDE.
BUT WHEN YOU LOOK AT THE ENTIRE
NEIGHBORHOOD, HOW MANY PEOPLE
ACTUALLY KNOW ALL THEIR
NEIGHBORS WITH THEIR COMMUNITY.
SAME TIME SHE DID HAVE
INTERACTIONS WITH THIS WOMAN,
MOST ABOUT THE GARDENING AND
ABOUT LANDSCAPING AND ABOUT
DICE.
NOT THE TYPE OF THINGS THAT
WOULD RAISE QUESTIONS OR ANY
KIND OF INTERACTIONS WITH HER
SON THAT WERE IN ANY KIND OF
OUTWARD WAY BOISTEROUS OR
SOMETHING THAT YOU MIGHT EXPECT
WOFTH STEM SOME SORT OF
CONFLICT.
WE'RE CONTINUING TO DIG OUT HERE
AND HOPEFULLY WE'LL HAVE SOME
MORE ANSWERS FOR YOU SOON.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
OBVIOUSLY, WHEN MOMS KIND OF GET
TOGETHER OR NEIGHBORS THEY MAY
SAY I'M HAVING TROUBLE WITH MY
TEENAGER.
THIS ISN'T GOING RIGHT.
THAT'S NOT GOING RIGHT.
BUT BASED ON THE INTERVIEWS
YOU'VE BEEN DOING AND THE
REPORTING THAT HASN'T COME UP
YET.
WE WANT TO CLARIFY THAT
AUTHORITIES HAVE NOT YET SAID
THAT ADAM LANZA HAD ANY SORT OF
MENTAL ILLNESS.
THERE HAVE BEEN REPORTS HE MAY
HAVE HAD SOME TYPE OF AN AUTISM
DISORDER BUT AGAIN, ALL THAT HAS
YET TO BE CONFIRMED.
WE'VE GOT MORE HOW TO DEAL WITH
YOUR CHILD'S EMOTIONS.
HOW DO YOU TALK TO YOUR KIDS.
AN EXPERT GIVES YOU TIPS ABOUT
WHAT TO SAY.
PLUS, DON LEMON BACK WITH US
LIVE FROM NEWTOWN.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS KAREN AND JEREMIAH.
THEY DON'T KNOW IT YET,
BUT THEY'RE GONNA FALL IN LOVE,
GET MARRIED,
HAVE A COUPLE OF KIDS,
[ children laughing ]
MOVE TO THE COUNTRY,
AND LIVE A LONG, HAPPY LIFE
TOGETHER
WHERE THEY ALMOST NEVER FIGHT
ABOUT MONEY.
[ dog barks ]
BECAUSE RIGHT AFTER
THEY GET MARRIED,
THEY'LL FIND
SOME RETIREMENT PEOPLE
WHO ARE PAID ON SALARY,
NOT COMMISSION.
THEY'LL GET
STRAIGHTFORWARD GUIDANCE
AND BE ABLE TO FOCUS ON OTHER
THINGS, LIKE EACH OTHER,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
>>> THOSE CHILDREN WHO WERE AT
THE SCHOOL AT THE TIME OF THE
SHOOTING WILL CERTAINLY HAVE A
LOT OF QUESTIONS, AND PARENTS
HAVE TO FIND A WAY TO ANSWER
THEM.
AND THAT IS WHY I WANT TO
BRINGING IN JEFF GARDERE TO TALK
ABOUT HOW ONE EXPLAINS THIS
TRAGEDY TO CHILDREN.
HE'S A CLINICAL PSYCHOLOGIST.
BEFORE WE TALK ABOUT THIS
EXPLAINING THIS TO A CHILD,
WE'VE BEEN TALKING A LOT ABOUT
GUN LAWS IN THIS COUNTRY AND
ABOUT SOMEHOW MAKING SURE THAT
THE -- THEY DON'T GET IN THE
HANDS OF THE WRONG PEOPLE.
I THINK IT'S JUST AS IMPORTANT
TO TALK ABOUT MENTAL HEALTH, A
SUBJECT THAT'S BEEN COMING UP
OVER AND OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
SO WHERE DO WE START HERE THEN?
BECAUSE I GUESS IS NEBULOUS A
RIGHT, RIGHT WORD OR COMPLEX IS
PROBABLY THE RIGHT WORD WHEN IT
COMES TO DEALING WITH MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES.
>> YES, IT IS VERY COMPLEX.
AND THIS BRINGS UP A VERY
EXCELLENT POINT AND I'M SO GLAD,
DON, THAT YOU'RE ASKING THIS
QUESTION.
YOU HAD A PREVIOUS GUEST WHO
SAID LOOK, WHEN IT COMES TO
BACKGROUND CHECKS, WE HAVE TO
LOOK AT MINNESOTA MULL FACIC
PERSONALITY INVENTORY WHICH
GIVES US A BROAD SPECTRUM AS TO
WHO THE PERSON IS, SOME OF THE
PSYCHOLOGICAL PROJECTIVE TESTS
AND SO ON.
HE IS RIGHT ON WITH THAT BECAUSE
RIGHT NOW ONE OF THE ONLY
QUESTIONS ASKED WHEN YOU'RE
GETTING A GUN PERMIT DURING THE
GUN APPLICATION IS, HAVE YOU
EVER BEEN DECLARED INCOMPETENT
OR HAVE YOU EVER BEEN
INVOLUNTARY PLACED IN A MENTAL
INSTITUTION.
AND MOST PEOPLE WILL JUST SAY NO
AND LEAVE IT ALONE.
THEN THE PERSON WILL CALL IN A
BACKGROUND CHECK WITH THE FBI OR
SOME OTHER AGENCY.
BUT WHAT WE KNOW IS, THREE
MILLION PEOPLE HAVE BEEN PLACED
IN HOSPITALS FOR PSYCHIATRIC
REASONS.
BUT ONLY 90,000 OF THOSE PEOPLE
ARE IN THAT DATABASE.
SO THERE'S A HUGE HOLE THERE.
AND SO WHAT WE'RE LOOKING AT IS
YEAH, OKAY, SO LET'S LOOK AT
PEOPLE WITH SEVERE MENTAL
ILLNESS BUT A LOT OF TIMES THE
PEOPLE THAT COMMIT THESE CRIMES,
YOU CAN'T DOCUMENT THAT THEY
WERE IN A HOSPITAL.
THEY WERE NEVER IN A PSYCHIATRIC
HOSPITAL.
THEY WERE FLYING UNDER THE
RADAR.
AND WE KNOW THERE HAVE BEEN
OTHER INSTANCES WHERE PEOPLE
HAVE NOT BEEN PSYCHOTIC WHO HAVE
TAKEN MATTERS INTO THEIR OWN
HANDS AND BEEN INVOLVED WITH
MASS MURDERS AND THESE HAVE --
THESE PEOPLE ONLY HAVE
PERSONALITY DISORDERS AND ARE
NOT PSYCHOTIC.
SO I THINK WE'RE KIND OF MISSING
THE BOAT HERE.
THERE ARE VIOLENT PEOPLE WHO
DON'T HAVE SEVERE MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES.
JUST TO LOOK AT PEOPLE WITH
MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES AS BEING
THE ONES WHO SHOULDN'T HAVE
GUNS, I THINK IT HAS TO GO MUCH
BROADER THAN THAT AND WE HAVE TO
LOOK AT THE WHOLE PERSONALITY,
NOT PEOPLE JUST WITH MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES.
>> THERE YOU GO.
LISTEN, IF YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT
THE GUN LAWS IN THIS COUNTRY AND
SOMEHOW TRYING TO KEEP THEM OUT
OF THE HANDS OF PEOPLE WHO ARE
NOT SUITABLE TO OWN THEM OR OH
SES THEM, THE TWO -- IT'S NOT
MUTUALLY EXCLUSIVE.
ONE HAS TO DO WITH THE OTHER.
YOU WANT TO KEEP IT OUT OF THE
HANDS OF PEOPLE THAT AREN'T
MENTALLY STABLE.
THAT'S A CONVERSATION WE SHOULD
BE HAVING AROUND THE COUNTRY AND
QUITE FRANKLY OUR CONGRESS
SHOULD BE HAVING, AS WELL.
LET'S TALK ABOUT THE CHILDREN
NOW, THE YOUNGEST AMONG US,
SADLY 20 OF THEM DIED IN THIS.
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN THIS KIND OF
TRAGEDY TO A CHILD, ESPECIALLY A
CHILD WHO MAY HAVE WITNESSED
THIS, WHO WAS IN THE SCHOOL?
>> WELL, IT'S IMPORTANT TO KNOW
THAT TOO OFTEN, WE THINK
CHILDREN ARE RESILIENT AND IF
THEY'RE NOT TALKING ABOUT
SOMETHING, THEN THEY'RE NOT
EXPERIENCING IT, BUT THE KIDS IN
THAT SCHOOL, THE KIDS IN THAT
TOWN AND EVEN THE KIDS WHO ARE
IN OTHER CITIES ARE PROCESSING
THIS, ARE GOING THROUGH THIS,
AND THEY NEED FOR US TO REACH
OUT TO THEM SO THE FIRST AND
MOST IMPORTANT THING YOU CAN DO
STOG FIND OUT WHAT IT IS THAT
THEY KNOW ABOUT THIS TRAUMA,
WHAT IT IS THAT THEY ARE
THINKING ABOUT, WHAT IT IS THAT
THEY WOULD LIKE TO KNOW, AND
THEN BEGIN YOUR DISCUSSION THERE
INSTEAD OF GOING INTO A STRAIGHT
DIALOGUE OR PREACHING TO THEM AS
TO WHAT HAS HAPPENED AND THE
EVILS OF GUNS AND SO ON.
THEY MAY NOT BE THERE YET.
SO BE WHERE THEY ARE, AND BEGIN
THAT CONVERSATION WITH THEM.
AND SECONDLY, AND MOST
IMPORTANTLY, IT'S NOT ONE
CONVERSATION, DON.
YOU AND I HAVE TALKED ABOUT THIS
BEFORE.
IT REALLY IS A SERIES OF
CONVERSATIONS AND IT'S NOT THAT
YOU SIT HERE AND I'LL SIT THERE
AND LET'S TALK, BUT IT'S ABOUT
DOING OTHER ACTIVITIES, COOKING
WITH YOUR KIDS, EXERCISING WITH
YOUR KIDS, PLAYING WITH YOUR
KIDS.
AND THEN BRINGING UP THESE
SERIES OF CONVERSATIONS AND
MAKING SURE IT'S INTERACTIONAL
WHERE THEY'RE DOING A LOT OF THE
TALKING, YOU'RE DOING A LOT OF
THE LISTENING, BUT BEING HONEST
WITH THEM AND LETTING THEM KNOW
THAT THIS IS SOMETHING VERY
DIFFICULT FOR YOU TO DISCUSS
WITH THEM, TOO, AND IT'S OKAY TO
SAY, I DON'T KNOW WHEN IT COMES
TO CERTAIN THINGS WHY CERTAIN
THINGS HAPPEN, BUT LET'S TALK
ABOUT IT, LET'S TRY TO FIGURE IT
OUT TOGETHER.
THAT'S THE IMPORTANT THING, THE
COMMUNICATION.
>> LISTEN, JEFF, IF AT THIS
POINT WHAT HAPPENED YESTERDAY IN
THIS COUNTRY ALL OF US
WITNESSING IT, IF WE CAN'T SIT
DOWN AND HAVE A CONVERSATION
RIGHT NOW, I DON'T KNOW WHEN
WE'RE GOING TO BE ABLE TO DO IT.
IF THIS DOESN'T MOVE PEOPLE TO
DO THAT, I DON'T KNOW WHAT WILL.
>> WELL, WE HAVE TO STRIKE WHILE
THE IRON IS HOT.
I'M ONE OF THE PEOPLE WHO SAID
PERHAPS YESTERDAY IT WAS TOO
SOON TO BE TALKING ABOUT WHAT
SOCIETY NEEDS TO DO IN ORDER TO
ADDRESS THESE ISSUES.
IT'S NOT TOO SOON NOW.
WE WANT PEOPLE TO GRIEVE.
WE WANT THEM TO TALK ABOUT WHAT
THEY'RE EXPERIENCING.
GOD BLESS THOSE FAMILIES THERE
IN CONNECTICUT.
BUT WE HAVE TO BEGIN THE
DISCUSSION NOW, STRIKE WHILE
THAT IRON IS HOT.
>> YEAH, LISTEN.
I UNDERSTAND WHAT YOU'RE SAYING.
I THINK IT'S DISRESPECTFUL NOT
TO TALK ABOUT IT WHEN 20 KIDS
HAVE DIED, SIX ADULTS.
I THINK IT'S DISRESPECT IN NOT
TO TALK ABOUT THE ISSUE INSTEAD
OF SAYING LET'S NOT THE RIGHT
TIME.
IT IS THE RIGHT TIME.
WHEN IS IT GOING TO BE THE RIGHT
TIME?
JEFF, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I WANT TO GET BACK TO DEB
FEYERICK IN ATLANTA.
DEB HAS OTHER INFORMATION, SOL
STORIES WE'RE FOLLOWING TODAY.
>> OKAY, THANKS, DON.
OBVIOUSLY A VERY DIFFICULT
CONVERSATION TO HAVE WITH KIDS
BUT WE START WITH DETAILS ON A
DEVELOPING STORY.
DOCTORS ARE MONITORING SECRETARY
OF STATE HILLARY CLINTON FOR A
CONCUSSION.
CLINTON APPARENTLY HIT HER HEAD
AFTER SHE FAINTED.
HER OFFICE SAYS CLINTON WAS
DEHYDRATED FROM A STOMACH VIRUS
AND SHE'S RESTING COMFORTABLY AT
HOME.
SHE WILL WORK FROM HOME NEXT
WEEK FOLLOWING HER DOCTOR'S
RECOMMENDATIONS.
SHE CANCELED A TRIP TO THE
MIDDLE EAST AND NORTH AFRICA
LAST WEEK BECAUSE OF THE STOMACH
VIRUS.
>>> FORMER SOUTH AFRICAN
PRESIDENT NELSON MANDELA ALSO
RECOVERING RIGHT NOW AFTER
HAVING SURGERY TO REMOVE
GALLSTONES TODAY.
THE PROCEDURE WAS SUCCESSFUL.
HE REMAINS HOSPITALIZED FOR A
RECURRING LUNG INFECTION.
THE 94-YEAR-OLD ANTI-APARTHEID
ICON HAS NOT APPEARED IN PUBLIC
SINCE THE 2010 WORLD CUP THAT
WAS HOSTED BY SOUTH AFRICA.
>>> IN EGYPT, PRESIDENT MOHAMED
MORSI CAST HIS BALLOT TODAY FOR
A NEW DRAFT CONSTITUTION.
VOTERS THERE DECIDING WHETHER
THE CONTROVERSIAL DOCUMENT
SHOULD GO INTO EFFECT.
THE DAYS LEADING UP TO THE VOTE
HAVE BEEN MARRED BY MANY
PROTESTS AND VIOLENCE.
DON NOW IS LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WITH A LOT MORE.
>> DEB, THANK YOU.
WE'LL GET BACK TO YOU.
YOU KNOW THIS TRAGEDY HAS
SPARKED A NEW STAGE IN THE
DEBATE OVER GUN LAWS IN THIS
COUNTRY.
SOME OF THAT DEBATE TAKING PLACE
ONLINE.
SO JOSH, YOU'VE HEARD ME HERE
ONLINE, THE PEOPLE ON SOCIAL
MEDIA I'M SURE HEARING ME IN THE
BREAK.
I GET A CHANCE TO CHECK IT.
GUESS WHAT, PEOPLE ARE EAGER TO
HAVE THIS CONVERSATION EVEN THE
PEOPLE WHO SAY YOU KNOW WHAT,
THE GUN LAWS ARE FINE THE WAY
THEY ARE NOW AND THE FOLKS HOG
ARE SAYING THEY'RE NOT FINE THE
WAY THEY ARE.
IT'S OBVIOUSLY WE NEED TO TALK
ABOUT AND IT WOULD BE VERY
DISRESPECTFUL NOT TO TALK ABOUT
IT AT THIS POINT AND SOCIAL
MEDIA IS DOING ITTING.
>> PEOPLE CAN SAY WHAT THEY WANT
WHETHER THIS CONVERSATION SHOULD
EXIST RIGHT NOW OR NOT.
CAT'S OUT OF THE BAG.
PEOPLE ARE TALKING ABOUT THIS.
AND THE DEBATE ISN'T BETWEEN
PEOPLE WHO SAY GUN LAWS ARE
PERFECT AND DON'T NEED TO BE
CHANGED.
IT'S MORE PEOPLE WHO SAY WE NEED
TO FOCUS ON GUN LAWS WHILE
OTHERS SAY WE NEED TO FOCUS ON
THINGS LIKE MENTAL ILLNESS.
THIS DEBATE IS NOW BECOMING A
PART OF THE STORY AS THE COUNTRY
AND THE WORLD REALLY FEEL THIS
TRAUMA.
LET MOO TAKE YOU FIRST TO A
QUOTE WE HAVE NOW, A LITTLE
PIECE OF SOUND FROM AN
I-REPORTER WHO SAYS HE'S A BIG
FAN OF GUN RIGHTS.
>> YOU KNOW, PEOPLE TALK ABOUT
THE SECOND AMENDMENT.
THEY TALK ABOUT THE RIGHT TO
BEAR ARMS.
I TRULY BELIEVE IN THAT.
I TRULY BELIEVE THAT AMERICA
SHOULD ARM THE SCHOOLS.
OUR TEACHERS OUR PRINCIPALS
SHOULD HAVE -- SHOULD HAVE A WAY
TO DEFEND OUR CHILDREN.
>> SUGGESTIONS OF ARMING PEOPLE
IN SCHOOLS, SOMETHING A LOT OF
PEOPLE ARE PUTTING OUT THERE.
I WANT TO BRING YOU AN EXAMPLE
FROM THE OTHER SIDE, ONE OF OUR
REPORTER WHO'S WANTS A WHOLE
BUNCH OF NEW GUN LAWS.
>> FIRST ONE IS OWNING LIVE
AMMUNITION.
I THINK THAT SHOULD BE MADE
ILLEGAL.
PEOPLE THAT DO OWN, WANT TO OWN
A GUN OR SOME KIND OF A FIREARM
FOR THE PROTECTION OF THEMSELVES
OR THEIR FAMILY SHOULD OWN ONE.
HOWEVER, THEY SHOULD NOT HAVE TO
HAVE LETHAL AMMUNITION.
THERE ARE STUN GUNS, RUBBER
BULLETS, TASER GUNS THAT CAN BE
USED IN A CRITICAL SITUATION.
>> LET ME SHOW YOU A FEW THINGS
COMING IN ON TWITTER.
I KNOW DON IS HAVING
CONVERSATIONS, AS WELL.
HERE'S ONE XAX OF AU TWEET TO ME
FROM BRIAN.
IT MAZES ME HOW POLITICAL THIS
TURNED POLITICAL ABOUT GUN
CONTROL.
ONE MORE HERE.
WHAT WE NEED ARE ARMED TRAINED
ADULTS IN THE SCHOOL
SYSTEM #MAKE THEM SAFE.
TIME FOR ONE MORE.
THIS IS A CONVERSATION GOING ON
ON TWITTER.
IT'S SAD BUT PEOPLE TRULY DON'T
CARE IF THEY WANTED TO END THE
VIOLENCE, THEY HAD HAVE DONE
SOMETHING.
NOW I'M GOING TO CROSS ACROSS
THE SCREEN.
I WANT YOU TO ALL TO SEE HOW
MUCH COVERAGE WE HAVE AND HOW
POWERFUL SOME OF THESE PHOTOS
ARE.
THIS IS A SPREAD WE HAVE ON
CNN.COM.
IT INCLUDES PHOTOS PEOPLE
INCLUDING THE PRESIDENT ALL OVER
THE COUNTRY AND ALL OVER THE
WORLD MOURNING IN DIFFERENT
WAYS.
PICTURES FROM A LOT OF DIFFERENT
COUNTRIES AND STATES ALL OVER
THIS COUNTRY.
DON, THIS CONVERSATION IS
ALREADY HAPPENING, AND IT DOES
NEED TO BE LED BY PEOPLE WHO
REALLY KNOW WHAT THEY'RE TALKING
ABOUT AND KNOW THE SPECS OF HOW
GUN LAWS CURRENTLY OPERATE OF
WHAT NEEDS TO BE DONE OF WHAT
MAY HAVE OR MAY NOT HAVE APPLIED
IN THE CASES OF OTHER RECENT
HORRIFYING INCIDENTS.
WE'RE SEEING AN ABSOLUTELY
HORRIFIC TIME LINE.
I'LL TELL YOU ONE MORE THING,
WITH ALL THE MASS SHOOTINGS WE
HAVE THIS IN COUNTRY WITH ALL
THE SCHOOL SHOOTINGS WE HAVE
SEEN, WE TAKE YOU THROUGH HOW
MANY THERE HAVE BEEN, IT'S A
NIGHTMARE.
THE FACT IS I HAVE NEVER SEEN A
MOMENT LIKE THIS IN THIS COUNTRY
IN WHICH PEOPLE SEEM TO BE
REALIZING IT IS SO DEEP, IS IT
IS SUCH A HUGE NATIONAL PROBLEM
THAT IT'S ABSOLUTELY TIME THAT
WE ACT.
I THINK WE MIGHT SEE SOME ACTION
THIS TIME.
>> IT IS -- IT'S LISTEN, JOSH,
I'VE NEVER SEEN PEOPLE AS
PASSIONATE ABOUT IT ON SOCIAL
MEDIA.
LET'S TALK MORE ABOUT THIS.
DON'T GO ANYWHERE.
SOMEONE SAYS SALUTE.
I SALUTE YOU FOR USING THIS
PLATFORM TO DISCUSS OUR OBSCENE
GUN LAWS AND DEMAND A COMMON
SENSE APPROACH.
WHY SHOULD WE HAVE A DEBATE
ABOUT GUN CONTROL OR MENTAL
HEALTH TREATMENT?
THERE ARE EQUALLY IMPORTANT
COMMON SENSE.
KEEP ASKING THE QUESTION.
WHY ISN'T THIS THE RIGHT TIME TO
HAVE A CONVERSATION?
WHEN WOULD THERE BE A BETTER
TIME?
JOSH, I THINK SOCIAL MEDIA HAS
IT RIGHT, RIGHT NOW.
IF WE CAN'T HAVE A CONVERSATION
AT THE RIGHT TIME ISN'T AFTER 20
KIDS WERE SHOT UP IN THE SCHOOL
AND KILLED, THEN WHEN IS THE
RIGHT TIME?
I THINK SOCIAL MEDIA HAS IT
RIGHT.
>> THE NEW YORK MAYOR MICHAEL
BLOOMBERG, IF YOU'RE WATCHING US
RIGHT NOW, HE'S APPLAUDING.
THIS IS A MESSAGE HE AND SOME
OTHER PEOPLE IN PROMINENT
POSITIONS HAVE BEEN PUSHING FOR
A LONG TIME.
THE ARGUMENT HAS BEEN WELL, IN
THE WAKE OF SUCH HORROR, WE
SHOULDN'T BE HAVING THIS
CONVERSATION RIGHT AWAY.
FOCUS ON THE VICTIMS.
WHALE SEVERAL POLITICIANS AND
PEOPLE LIKE YOU AND I POINT OUT,
THE CONVERSATION DOESN'T HAPPEN
A MONTH OR TWO MONTHS LATER.
YOU JUST ON WITH EVERYTHING ELSE
IN THE COUNTRY AND THEN WE HAVE
ANOTHER ONE.
IF THE CONVERSATION IS GOING TO
HAPPEN, IT'S GOING TO BE AT A
TIME WHEN WE'RE FEELING THIS
PASSION.
I'M A PARENT.
I'M HORRIFIED AS I ALWAYS AM
EVERY TIME.
THE THOUGHT THERE'S ANY HUMAN
BEING CAPABLE OF THIS SHOWS
WE'VE GOT TO DO SOMETHING.
I DON'T PRETEND TO HAVE THE
ANSWERS BUT WE ASK FOR THE
ANSWERS.
>> IF YOU WANT TO BE RESPECTFUL
OF THE VICTIMS THEN WE CAN DO
THAT, BUT WE ALSO CAN BE
RESPECTFUL OF THE VICTIMS BY
MAKING SURE THERE AREN'T OTHER
VICTIMS IN THE FUTURE.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> COLUMBINE HIGH SCHOOL,
VIRGINIA TECH, NOW SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
WITH EVERY SCHOOL SHOOTING,
EVERY PARENT THINKS IT COULD
HAVE BEEN MY CHILD.
THE WHAT, THE HOW AND WHERE THIS
COULD SAVE YOUR CHILD'S LIFE.
HAVING YOU SHIP MY GIFTS
COULDN'T BE EASIER.
WELL, HAVING A TON OF LOCATIONS
DOESN'T HURT.
AND A SANTA TO BOOT!
[ chuckles ]
RIGHT, BABY.
OH, SIR.
THAT IS A CUSTOMER.
OH...SORRY ABOUT THAT.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
FEDEX OFFICE.
That was ME...
the day I learned I had
to start insulin
for my type 2 diabetes.
ME...
thinking my only option was the
vial and syringe dad used.
And ME...
discovering once-daily
Levemir® FlexPen.
FlexPen® is prefilled.
Doesn't need
refrigeration
for up to
42 days.
No drawing from a vial.
Dial the exact dose.
Inject by pushing a button.
FlexPen® is insulin delivery...
MY way.
Levemir® (insulin detemir
[rDNA origin] injection)
is a long-acting insulin
used to control high blood sugar
in adults and children
with diabetes and is not
recommended to treat
diabetic ketoacidosis.
Do not use Levemir® if
you are allergic
to any of its ingredients.
The most common side effect
is low blood sugar,
which may cause
symptoms such as sweating,
shakiness, confusion,
and headache.
Severe low blood sugar can be
serious and life threatening.
Ask your healthcare provider
about alcohol use,
operating machinery, or driving.
Other possible side
effects include
injection site reactions.
Tell your healthcare provider
about all medicines you take
and all of your
medical conditions.
Get medical help right away
if you experience
serious allergic
reactions, such as body rash,
trouble with breathing, fast
heartbeat, or sweating.
With FlexPen®... say good night
to vial and syringe.
Ask your doctor about
Levemir® FlexPen.
Covered by
90% of insurance plans,
including Medicare.
Find your co-pay at
MyFlexPen.com.
WANT TO GIVE YOU THE VERY LATEST
NOW ON THE SCHOOL SHOOTING HERE
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, THAT
LEFT 20 CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS
DEAD.
ALL VIPS OF THE SHOOTING RAMPAGE
HAVE BEEN IDENTIFIED.
ALL OF THOSE PEOPLE, THE LOVED
ONES, THEY WERE SOMEONE LOVED
ONES AND THEY HAVE BEEN
IDENTIFIED.
THEIR NAMES ARE EXPECTED TO BE
RELEASED SHORTLY.
POLICE HAVE DETERMINED THAT THE
SUSPECTED SHOOTER FORCED HIS WAY
INTO SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
POLICE NOW SAY THREE GUNS WERE
FOUND INSIDE THE SCHOOL NEAR THE
BODY OF THE SUSPECT.
THEY SAY HE KILLED HIMSELF.
THE GUNS ARE A GLOCK, A SIX
SAUER, AND A BUSHMASTER RIFLE.
POLICE HAVE TOLD US THEY NOW
KNOW WHICH WEAPON HE USED TO
KILL HIMSELF BUT THEY HAVE NOT
RELEASED THAT INFORMATION TO THE
MEDIA.
A SAFE TOWN, THAT'S THE PHRASE
RESIDENTS USED TO DESCRIBE
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, TO
DESCRIBE THIS IDYLLIC NEW
ENGLAND TOWN.
NOW, THE ENTIRE WORLD MOURNS FOR
NEWTOWN AND TRIES TO MAKE SENSE
OF THIS INCREDIBLE TRAGEDY.
AND THE IMAGE OF THE TOWN LIKE
SO MANY LIVES ARE SHATTERED.
>> IT WAS TERRIFYING.
I'M STILL TERRIFIED.
I THINK I'M STILL IN SHOCK ABOUT
IT ALL.
I STILL DON'T KNOW EVERYTHING
THAT HAPPENED.
I KNOW THERE'S SOME PEOPLE
MISSING THAT HAVE BEEN TAKEN TO
THE HOSPITAL.
IT'S TERRIFYING.
YOU KNOW, YOU'RE RUSHING OVER
HERE AND YOU CAN'T GET TO WHERE
YOU NEED TO GO.
>> WHEN WE FIRST ARRIVED THERE,
THERE WAS NOT A LOT OF SECURITY
TO GUARD.
AND THERE WERE THREE CHILDREN
THAT CAME OUT, ONE OF THEM
WAS -- HAD A VERY BLOODY FACE.
IT WAS VERY VIOLENT SCENE AND
THERE WERE TWO OTHER ONES THAT
THEY WERE, YOU KNOW, THEY WERE
IN THE ARMS OF A SAY THE
TROOPER.
THEY DID NOT MOVE.
THEIR FACE WAS VERY PALE.
IT WAS VERY TRAGIC.
>> DEB FEYERICK IS BACK AT THE
CNN HEADQUARTERS IN ATLANTA.
NO MATTER HOW MANY TIMES I COVER
THESE STORIES WHEN I SEE THE
FAMILY MEMBERS OF SOME OF THE
VICTIMS I WONDER HOW THEY'RE
EVEN ABLE TO TALK AND STILL
STANDING AT THIS POINT.
>> YEAH, IT TAKES EVERY OUNCE OF
STRENGTH YOU HAVE NOT TO JUST
GIVE UP AND GIVE IN.
AND A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE GOING TO
WRESTLE WITH THE PAIN FOR A
VERY, VERY LONG TIME.
WE'VE SEEN IT OVER AND OVER
AGAIN, DON.
NEVER AGAIN, WE SAY THAT AFTER
EVERY SHOOTING, BUT YET, HERE WE
ARE ONCE AGAIN.
MASS SCHOOL SHOOTINGS NOT JUST A
NIGHTMARE BUT A REALITY THAT ARE
BECOMING ALL TOO FAMILIAR.
WHAT WE'RE ABOUT TO SHOW YOU
COULD SAVE YOUR CHILD'S LIFE.
BRIAN TODD TALKS WITH AN
SECURITY EXPERT.
>> A NIGHTMARE SCENARIO FOR ANY
SCHOOL SECURITY OFFICIAL.
MICHAEL HAS IDEAS HOW TO AVOID
MASS CASUALTIES IF A GUN MAB IS
IN YOUR SCHOOL.
HOW DO YOU RESPOND IF THERE ARE
KIDS ALL AROUND?
>> THAT'S WHERE THE TRAINING
COMES IN.
>> HE IS HEAD OF SECURITY FOR
PRINCE GEORGES PUBLIC SCHOOLS IN
MARYLAND.
A FORMER DEPUTY POLICE CHIEF WHO
ONCE HAD TO LOCK DOWN A SCHOOL.
HE TOOK US THROUGH AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL THAT OFFICIALS DIDN'T
WANT US TO NAME.
SHOWED US WHAT TO DO IF THE
NIGHTMARE UNFOLDS.
>> EXITS ARE KEY.
FIND THE NEAREST ONE.
>> ABSOLUTELY, ABSOLUTELY.
AND IT'S IMPORTANT TO BE
FAMILIAR WITH THE BUILDING.
THAT'S WHY AGAIN, WE ENCOURAGE
JUST LITTLE THINGS, JUST A
BUILDING FAMILIARIZATION, JUST
WALKING THE OUTSIDE OF THE
BUILDING SO YOU KNOW IF YOU
LEAVE THIS PARTICULAR DOOR, IF
IT COMES TO A CREEK OR PARKING
LOT OR A BUSY INTERSECTION.
>> ADULTS AND STUDENTS HE SAYS
HAVE TO HAVE THAT EXIT
AWARENESS.
BUT IF YOU'RE STUCK INSIDE,
MICHAEL BLOW SAYS WHILE
BATHROOMS MAY BE A TEMPTING
PLACE TO HIDE AT FIRST, NOT A
GOOD IDEA.
AS YOU CAN SEE, A VERY CONFINED
SPACE AND USUALLY NO WAY OUT.
COURTYARDS HE SAYS ARE EQUALLY
TEMPTING BUT ALSO NOT THE BEST
PLACES BECAUSE THEY'RE OFTEN
ENCLOSED.
>> IF THIS IS A CLASSROOM,
THERE'S A GUNMAN, WE'VE HEARD
SHOTS, WE DON'T KNOW WHERE HE
IS, WHAT DO WE DO?
DO WE LOCK, TURN LIGHTS OFF,
CLOSE WINDOWS?
>> CERTAINLY, THERE ARE A HOST
OF THINGS WE WOULD DO IN AN PLJS
THAT WOULD INCLUDE LOCKING DOORS
TO MAKE SURE THAT WE ARE ABLE TO
FORTIFY THAT ENTRANCEWAY AS BEST
AS WE CAN, AGAIN, IF THERE ARE
NO SAFE ALTERNATIVES FOR
EVACUATING THE BUILDING, AND
THAT WAY, IF SOMEONE WAS TO WALK
BY THE ROOM THAT THEY WON'T HAVE
AN EASY SITE PICTURE OF ANYONE
THAT IS IN THE ROOM.
>> ADULTS IN THE ROOM HE SAYS
SHOULD TALK THE KIDS THROUGH IT
AS CALMLY AS POSSIBLE.
>> WHAT ABOUT LARGE ROOMS LIKE
GYMS?
YOU GO IN, AVOID IT?
>> AGAIN, THERE'S NOT A LOT OF
PLACES TO CONCEAL YOURSELVES BUT
THERE'S A WAY TO GET TO THE
OTHER SIDE OF THE BUILDING.
>> HE DIDN'T WANT TO GIVEAWAY
TOO MANY PREEMPTIVE SECURITY
MEASURES BUT SOMETIMES THEY USE
WANDING DEVICES TO SCREEN
STUDENTS.
HE SAYS SOME OF THE BEST
SCREENING IS AWARENESS OF WHO IS
TROUBLED, WHO IS BEING BULL
AUDIO, THE RADAR UP FOR
POTENTIAL ASSAILANTS.
BRIAN TODD, PRINCE GEORGES
COUNTY, MARYLAND.
>> AFTER THIS ALL HAPPENED
YESTERDAY, THAT WAS ONE OF THE
FIRST THINGS THAT I LIKE SO MANY
OTHER PARENTS THOUGHT ABOUT.
THAT IS, YOU KNOW, ARE YOUR KIDS
REALLY READY?
DO THEY KNOW WHERE THE BACK
EXITS ARE?
DO THEY KNOW HOW TO SHELTER IN
PLACE?
DO THEY KNOW WHERE TO GO TO
HIDE.
I THINK OF THESE CHILDREN WHO
WENT INTO THE CLOSETS WITH THEIR
TEACHERS WHILE THE TEACHERS
TRIED TO KEEP THEM CALM.
IMAGINE THE GUNFIRE AND THESE
CHILDREN JUST COVERING THEIR
EARS WITH THEIR HANDS NOT EVEN
KNOWING WHAT TO DO.
DON, WE HEARD THAT STORY OF THAT
TEACHER WHO BASICALLY AFTER THE
SHOOTING STOPPED AND HEARD A
KNOCK ON THE DOOR SAYING IT'S
THE POLICE OPEN UP, SHE SAID NO,
NO, NO, SHOW ME IDENTIFICATION
AND THAT'S WHEN SHE OPEN THE
DOOR.
SOMETHING THAT SIMPLE SKROP
POTENTIALLY SAVED THEIR LIFE HAD
IT BEEN SOMEONE ELSE, DON.
>> MY GOSH.
IT'S SUCH A HORRIFIC TRAGEDY.
THANK YOU, DEB FEYERICK.
INVESTIGATORS WILL BE BACK AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL FOR
AT LEAST ANOTHER DAY OR TWO
TRYING TO PEAS TOGETHER THIS
HORRIFIC PUZZLE.
TO GIVE US A BETTER
UNDERSTANDING OF WHAT HAPPENED
JOSH LEVS IS HERE WITH A VIRTUAL
LOOK AT THE SCHOOL.
>> I WANT TO SHOW EVERYONE THIS
AERIAL VIEW OF THE SCHOOL.
THERE ARE A FEW DETAILS THAT ARE
VERY SIGNIFICANT FOR THIS
INVESTIGATION.
YOU ALL WILL UNDERSTAND IT BEST
WHEN YOU'RE LOOKING AT THE
SCHOOL.
I JUST WANT TO REMIND EVERYONE
THIS IS AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT.
THE IDEA THAT THIS IS NOW A
CRIME SCENE IS SO HORRIFIC.
THE FIRST THING TO NOTE, THE
OFFICIALS, THE POLICE ARE SAYING
THEY ARE SCOURING THE ENTIRE
SCHOOL EVERY ROOM, PRE BIT OF
IT.
IN THE PARKING LOT, THIS IS
THEIR WORDS THEY SAY EACH AND
EVERY CAR IN THE ENTIRE LOT IS
BEING INVESTIGATED.
WE DON'T KNOW IF THERE'S
SOMETHING SPECIFIC THEY'RE
LOOKING FOR.
WE DO KNOW THEY'RE LOOKING AT
EVERYTHING IN THIS ENTIRE AREA.
A LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIAL HAS
TOLD CNN THE GUNMANEN HAD SOME
KIND OF ALTERCATION WITH
OFFICIALS A FEW DAYS BEFORE OF
THIS.
ANOTHER THING HAS COME IN TODAY
THAT'S VERY IMPORTANT.
WE'VE BEEN FOLLOWING THE
TIMELINE CLOSELY BECAUSE IN AN
INCIDENT LIKE THIS EEB A
FRACTION OF A MINUTE MAKES A BIG
DIFFERENCE.
POLICE PUT OUT A STATEMENT
SAYING THE INITIAL 911 CALL CAME
AT 9:30 A.M.
I WANT PEOPLE TO UNDERSTAND WHY
THIS IS SO IMPORTANT.
THEY SAID IT WAS ABOUT 9:30 A.M.
AS WE UNDERSTAND IT, THAT'S THE
TIME THAT THE SCHOOL SECURITY
SYSTEM GETS PLACED ON AND DOORS
ARE SHUT.
SO WAS SOMETHING ALREADY
HAPPENING BY 9:30?
WAS THE GUNMAN STILL OUTSIDE AT
9:30?
THE OFFICIALS ARE SAYING HE
FORCED HIS WAY IN.
IF THE SYSTEM WAS ON, HOW DID HE
FORCE HIS WAY IN?
WHO IS DOES A PERSON FORCE HIS
WAY IN WITH GUNS WHEN A SCHOOL
HAS A SECURITY SYSTEM AND THEN
THEY'VE SAID THAT THERE WERE
WINDOWS THAT WERE SHATTERED BUT
NOT TO READ INTO THAT BECAUSE
WHEN THE AUTHORITIES WERE CALLED
TO THE SCENE, THEY HAD TO BURST
THEIR WAY IN.
SO WHEN WE SEE SHATTERED
WINDOWS, THAT DOESN'T MEAN THE
GUNMAN MIGHT HAVE GONE IN THAT
WAY.
THIS RAISES A GREAT NUMBER OF
QUESTIONS.
WE BELIEVE THE KILLINGS WERE IN
ONE AREA OF THE SCHOOL.
CLEARLY AUTHORITIES BELIEVE
THERE'S A POSSIBILITY OF FINDING
EVIDENCE ANYWHERE WITHIN IT.
WE'RE STAYING ON TOP OF ALL
THOSE DETAILS.
>> JOSH LEBS, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
WE'RE GOING TO BE HERE WITH YOU
ALL DAY AND PARDON THE AMBULANCE
OR THE SIREN GOING BY.
WE'RE GOING TO BE HERE WITH YOU
ALL DAY ALL EVENING LONG AS THE
NATION MOURNS.
WE'RE GOING TO BE LIVE FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, OUR
SOLEDAD O'BRIEN IS TALKING WITH
PEOPLE HERE IN THE COMMUNITY
WHERE EVERYBODY SEEMS TO KNOW
SOMEBODY IMPACTED BY THIS
TRAGEDY.
>> SOLEDAD'S UP NEXT.
STAY WITH US.
AMERICANS ARE ALWAYS READY TO
WORK HARD FOR A BETTER FUTURE.
SINCE AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL
WAS FOUNDED BACK IN 1894,
THEY'VE BEEN COMMITTED
TO PUTTING CLIENTS FIRST.
HELPING GENERATIONS
THROUGH TOUGH TIMES.
GOOD TIMES.
NEVER TAKING A BAILOUT.
THERE WHEN YOU NEED THEM.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
OVER THE CENTURIES.
THE STRENGTH OF
A GLOBAL FINANCIAL LEADER.
THE HEART OF
A ONE-TO-ONE RELATIONSHIP.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
>>> NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, SMALL
NEW ENGLAND TOWN THAT IS
SUDDENLY AND VERY TRAGICALLY
WELL-KNOWN.
THE BODIES OF 20 CHILDREN AND
SIX ADULTS KILLED BY AN ALLEGED
SHOOTER NAMED ADAM LANZA AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
YESTERDAY HAVE NOW BEEN REMOVED
FROM THAT SCHOOL.
THE VICTIMS HAVE BEEN
IDENTIFIED.
NOW NEWTOWN IS THE STORY OF A
TOWN THAT'S JUST BEEN SHATTERED.
NEIGHBORS AND FRIENDS ALL TRYING
TODAY TO MAKE SENSE OF SOMETHING
THAT ABSOLUTELY DEFIES MAKING
SENSE OF.
I SPOKE WITH ONE MAN WHOSE
FRIENDS LOST THEIR SON WHO WAS 5
YEARS OLD IN THE SHOOTING ON
FRIDAY.
>> THEY CAME TWO YEARS AGO FROM
ENGLAND AND VERY NICE FAMILY.
THEY FIT INTO THIS COMMUNITY
JUST PERFECTLY I WOULD SAY.
AND BASICALLY VERY CLOSE I WOULD
SAY.
THAT'S ALL I CAN SAY, CLOSE
FRIENDS, LIKE FAMILY.
>> HOW DID YOU FIND OUT THAT
THEIR SON HAD DIED?
>> LAST NIGHT.
WE -- WE FELT SOMETHING UNUSUAL
BECAUSE THEY DIDN'T RESPOND ON
THE PHONE CALLS OR MESSAGES.
AND LAST NIGHT, BASICALLY, THEY
CALLED US AND JUST TOLD US THEIR
SON NOT WITH US ANYMORE.
AND THAT'S HOW IT HAPPENED.
>> ALSO TODAY, I SPOKE WITH A
YOUNG MOTHER WHO WAS WAITING FOR
THE VICTIMS' NAMES TO BE
RELEASED ASKED HER IF SHE
THOUGHT SHE MIGHT KNOW SOME WHO
WERE ON THAT LIST WHO HAD BEEN
KILLED.
SHEARS WHAT SHE SAID.
>> UNFORTUNATELY, PROBABLY YES.
AND IT'S JUST A MATTER OF
FINDING OUT.
>> HOW WILL YOU HELP THEM?
WHAT CAN YOU POSSIBLY SAY THAT
HELPS ANOTHER PARENT WHO HAS
LOST A CHILD?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THAT IS.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THOSE WORDS
ARE.
>> I DON'T THINK THERE ARE
WORDS.
I THINK IT'S COMING TO THESE
MEMORIALS.
I THINK IT'S BEING CLOSE FROM
ONE FAMILY TO ANOTHER.
AND JUST BEING THERE.
YOU KNOW?
JUST HUGS.
I DON'T THINK THERE ARE ANY
WORDS.
>> AND SO TODAY, ANY ATTEMPT AT
ANY KIND OF RECOVERY BEGINS.
THIS IS A VERY CLOSE KNIT
COMMUNITY, NEWTOWN, A COMMUNITY
OF NEIGHBOR WHO'S KNOW EACH
OTHER EVEN IF THE KIDS DON'T GO
TO THE SAME SCHOOLS, THEY CARE
ABOUT EACH OTHER.
IT IS GOING TO TAKE AN
INCREDIBLE AMOUNT OF CARING TO
HELP THE FRIENDS AND FAMILIES OF
THE VICTIMS OF FRIDAY'S SHOOTING
BEGIN TO MOVE FORWARD AGAIN.
A LOT TO TALK ABOUT THIS MORNING
TO GIVE YOU AS MUCH INFORMATION
AS WE NOW KNOW ON WHAT HAPPENED
ON FRIDAY AND MORE ABOUT THE
SHOOTER IN THIS CASE.
LEASE SOME NEW INFORMATION WE'RE
WORKING ON.
A LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIAL IS
TELLING CNN IN FACT, THAT THE
ALLEGED SHOOTER HAD SOME SORT OF
ALTERCATION WITH SOME OF THE
PEOPLE AT THE SCHOOL A FEW DAYS
BEFORE THE KILLINGS, AND JOE
JOHNSON JOINS ME WITH A LITTLE
BIT MORE ABOUT THIS.
WHAT HAPPENED IN THAT
ALTERCATION, JOE?
>> SOLEDAD, WE'VE BEEN DEALING
WITH INFORMATION THAT'S ALL OVER
THE PLACE.
INVESTIGATORS THOUGH HAVE BEEN
TOLD THAT ADAM LANZA HAD SOME
TYPE OF ALTERCATION AT THE
SCHOOL ON THE DAY BEFORE THE
PASS KER.
NOT CLEAR RIGHT NOW WHAT THAT
MAY HAVE BEEN ABOUT.
WE'VE BEEN REACHING OUT TO
AUTHORITIES TO TRY TO EXPAND ON
THAT.
GOTTEN NO MORE DETAILS.
THE REPORTING ON THIS HAS BEEN
ALL OVER THE PLACE BUT THIS
SOURCE IS TELLING ME ON THE
GROUND THAT THEY DON'T THINK THE
STORY OF THAT ALTERCATION IS BAD
INFORMATION.
SO LOOKING TO LEARN MORE HOW
MANY PEOPLE MAY HAVE BEEN
INVOLVED AND OBVIOUSLY, THE
SOURCE OF IT, SOLEDAD.
>> YEAH, WE HEARD IN THE PRESS
CONFERENCE A LITTLE BIT EARLIER
TODAY, JOE, THAT THERE WAS LOTS
OF EVIDENCE AND AT SOME POINT
THEY WOULD BE ABLE TO SORT OF
PEEL BACK AS THEY DESCRIBED IT,
THE PIECES OF THE ONION AND BE
ABLE TO EXPLAIN HOPEFULLY HOW
AND WHY ALL OF THIS HAPPENED.
SO JOE, WE KNOW THERE'S A LITTLE
MORE INFORMATION ABOUT THE GUNS
THAT WERE INVOLVED IN THE
SHOOTING.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW?
>> THE GUN INVESTIGATION
CONTINUES.
A FEDERAL SOURCE TELLING ME THAT
THE TRACING OPERATION HAS NOT
BEEN COMPLETED ON THE GUNS
CONFISCATED IN THIS CRIME.
THAT TRACE GOES BACK TO THE
MANUFACTURER THROUGH THE
DISTRIBUTOR AND ALL THE BUYERS.
AS OF THIS MORNING, THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTER
IDENTIFIED AS ADAM LANZA HAD
ACCESS, WE'RE TOLD, TO A TOTAL
OF SIX GUNS.
THAT'S UP FROM THREE WE WERE
HEARING LAST NIGHT.
THE LATEST IS THAT THREE OF THE
FIREARMS WERE FOUND INSIDE THE
SCHOOL WITH THE SHOOTER ALONG
WITH A GLOCK, SIX SAUER,
BUSHMASTER, THOSE THREE WEAPONS
WERE FOUND INSIDE THE SCHOOL AND
WERE LEGALLY PURCHASED BY HIS
MOTHER NANCY, WHO WAS FOUND
DECEASED YESTERDAY.
THE OTHER THREE WEAPONS,
ACCORDING TO SUSAN CANDIOTTI
INCLUDE A .45 CALIBER HENRY
REPEATING RIFLE, A .22 CALIBER
MARLIN RIFLE AND A .30 CALIBER
INFIELD RIFLE NOT CLEAR WHETHER
THOSE GUNS WERE FOUND IN THE CAR
THAT LANZA HAD BEEN DRIVING OR
ELSEWHERE.
SO STILL TRYING TO SORT A LOT OF
THIS OUT.
THERE'S ALSO, OF COURSE, NEW
REPORTING BY CNN'S SUSAN
CANDIOTTI THAT IN FACT, THE
SHOOTER DID TRY TO PURCHASE SOME
TYPE OF A FIREARM EARLIER IN THE
WEEK AT A DICK'S SPORTING GOODS
STORE AND LOOKING TO SUSAN
CANDIOTTI FOR SOME MORE
REPORTING ON THAT.
BACK TO YOU.
>> THAT'S A LITTLE BIT OF A
CHANGE THEN BECAUSE WE HAD HEARD
EARLIER IN THE DAY REPORTS THAT
THAT BUSHMASTER WAS ACTUALLY IN
THE VEHICLE AND NEVER MADE ITS
WAY INTO THE SCHOOL.
SOUNDS LIKE THREE WEAPONS NOW IN
THE SCHOOL, ONE BEING THAT
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE BEING
REPORTED NOW IN THE SCHOOL.
JOE JOHNS FOR US, THANK YOU, FOR
THE UPDATE.
THE PEOPLE HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, ARE VERY SLOWLY
BEGINNING TO LEARN SOME OF THE
NAMES OF THE VICTIMS.
WE KNOW THE NUMBERS CERTAINLY.
20 CHILDREN ALL BETWEEN THE AGES
OF 5 AND 10.
THE SCHOOL WENT K TO 4.
20 KIRAN DIED IN THE SPREE.
THERE WERE SIX ADULTS WHO DIED,
AMONG THEM THE SCHOOL'S
PRINCIPAL.
HER NAME WAS DAWN HOCHSPRUNG.
SHE WAS 47 YEARS OLD, THE
PRINCIPAL SINCE 2010.
IN THAT TIME SHE HAD OVERHAULED
THE SCHOOL'S SECURITY SYSTEM.
SOME OF THE PARENTS WERE DELLING
US ABOUT THIS YESTERDAY.
SHE LEAVES BEHIND A HUSBAND AND
FIVE CHILDREN.
THOSE WHO REMEMBERED HER SAID
SHE CREATED AN ENVIRONMENT IN
HER SCHOOL THAT MADE PEOPLE FEEL
ACCEPTED AND IMPORTANT AND THEY
TRULY LOVED HER.
WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT ONE OF
THE TEACHERS TODAY.
VICKIE SOTO WAS KILLED WHILE
TRYING TO PROTECT AND HIDE THE
CHILDREN IN HER CLASS.
OUR CONNECTICUT REPORTER SARAH
HAGAN HAS MORE ON HER STORY.
>> I AM TOLD THAT VICTORIA LEE
SOTO WAS A GRADUATE FROM
STRATFORD HIGH SCHOOL THAT YOU
SEE BEHIND ME.
TAKE A LOOK AT THIS PHOTO.
THIS WAS A RECENT STAFF SCHOOL
PICTURE TAKEN JUST LAST WEEK AT
SANDY HOOK.
HER FAMILY SAYS SHE HAD HER
STUDENTS HUDDLED BEHIND HER
TRYING TO PROTECT THEM WHEN SHE
WAS SHOT AND KILLED.
THEY SAY SHE IS A HERO AND DID
EVERYTHING SHE CAN.
NER HUSBAND JAMES WILTSIE SAYS
ONE OF THE HARDEST PARTS YED WAS
WAITING TO SEE IF SHE WAS DEAD
OR ALIVE.
>> AT THAT POINT, IT WAS THE
HARDEST FOR THE WHOLE FAMILY,
JUST THE WAITING GIM RECEIVE
WORD ON WHAT HAPPENED TO
VICKIE'S GLAS CLASS.
>> I'M TOLD BILL FAMILY MEMBERS
THERE WILL BE A VIGIL HELD IN
HER MEMORY RIGHT HERE AT THE
HIGH SCHOOL AT 7:00 P.M.
TONIGHT.
WE'LL KEEP YOU UPDATED ON THIS
DEVELOPING STORY WITH ARE
CONTINUING COVERAGE.
>> IF YOU WANT MORE INFORMATION
HOW YOU CAN HELP THOSE AFFECTED
IN THIS TERRIBLE TRAGEDY, GO TO
CNN.COM/IMPACT.
YOU'LL HAVE LOTS OF INFORMATION
AND WAYS THAT YOU CAN HELP.
ALL OF THIS, OF COURSE, HAS LEFT
US WITH EVEN MORE QUESTIONS AND
ANSWERS RIGHT NOW ABOUT ANY
POSSIBLE MOTIVE ABOUT THE
SUSPECTED SHOOTER.
MARY SNOW HAS A CLOSER LOOK AT
HIM.
>> SHORTLY AFTER FRIDAY'S
HORRIFIC SHOOTINGS, POLICE AND
S.W.A.T. TEAMS DESCENDED UPON
THE LANZA HOME.
YOU CAN'T SEE IT.
IT'S BEHIND ME AND IT'S CLOSED
OFF BY POLICE.
AND INVESTIGATORS ARE NOW
SUGGESTING THAT THEY ARE PIECING
TOGETHER INFORMATION LEADING TO
POSSIBLE ANSWERS ABOUT HOW AND
WHY THIS HAPPENED.
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE OF THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE SAYING
THAT IN HIS WORDS, GOOD EVIDENCE
IS BEING RECOVERED.
BUT HE DID NOT GO INTO DETAIL.
IN TERMS OF THE WEAPONS USED, WE
DO KNOW THAT THREE WEAPONS WHERE
IS RECOVERED AT THE SCENE OF THE
SHOOTING NEAR THE SUSPECT'S
BODY.
THERE WERE TWO HANDGUNS AND A
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE.
CNN HAS BEEN REPORTING THAT
THOSE GUNS WERE PURCHASED BY HIS
MOTHER, NANCY LANZA.
THERE'S NOT MUCH WE DO KNOW
ABOUT NANCY LANZA.
WE SPOKE TO A NEIGHBOR EARLIER
IN THE DAY.
AND SHE SAID THAT SHE WILL KNEW
HER, BUT THERE WAS NOTHING OUT
OF THE ORDINARY THAT SHE COULD
SEE.
>> SHE WAS LIKE A NORMAL ANYBODY
ELSE IN THIS NEIGHBORHOOD.
YOU KNOW, DECORATE THE HOUSE AND
THE HOUSE WAS ALWAYS, YOU KNOW,
PRISTINE AND I MEAN, SHE WAS
JUST LIKE ANY OTHER HOUSEWIFE.
>> AS FOR ADAM LANZA, FORMER
CLASSMATES DESCRIBE HIM AS BEING
SMART, STUDENT, SOMEONE WHO WAS
QUIET, KEPT TO HIMSELF.
A NEIGHBOR HOB KNEW HIM IN
RECENT YEARS DESCRIBED HIM AS
TROUBLED.
MARY SNOW, CNN, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> AND AS WE TRY TO LEARN MORE
ABOUT THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER,
WE'RE ALSO LEARNING MORE ABOUT
SOME OF THE WEAPONS THAT ADAM
LANZA ALLEGEDLY USED TO TARGET
KINDERGARTENERNERS AND FIRST
GRADERS AT THE SCHOOL.
AUTHORITIES FOUND THREE OF THE
SIX GUNS NEAR LANZA'S BODY
INSIDE THE SCHOOL CLASSROOM.
THAT'S THE LATEST WE HAVE BEEN
LEARNING ABOUT THAT.
ALL THREE GUNS WERE OWNED AND
REGISTERED BY HIS MOTHER.
INVESTIGATORS RECOVERED THREE
OTHER RIFLES.
WE DON'T KNOW WHERE THOSE
WEAPONS WERE FOUND.
WE WANT TO GET THEFT AFTERNOON
TO MIKE BOUCHARD.
YOU SUPERVISED THE ATF'S
RESPONSE TO A TRAGIC KILLING
SPREE ABOUT TEN YEARS AGO, THE
BELTWAY SNIPER.
SO UNFORTUNATELY, YOU HAVE A LOT
OF EXPERIENCE IN THESE KINDS OF
HORRIFIC TRAGEDIES.
I WANT TO TALK SPECIFICALLY
ABOUT THE WEAPONS.
ORIGINALLY WE HAD HEARD THAT THE
BUSHMASTER 223, THE
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE HAD BEEN
LEFT IN THE CAR.
AND NOW WE NOW UNDERSTAND THAT
IT ACTUALLY WAS INSIDE THE
SCHOOL.
DOES THAT ANSWER SOME QUESTIONS
FOR YOU ABOUT THE LARGE NUMBER
OF SHOTS THAT PEOPLE REPORTED
HEARING AND THE AMOUNT OF DAMAGE
AND THE NUMBER OF PEOPLE WHO
WERE KILLED IN THIS SPREE?
>> WELL, SOLEDAD, I THINK IT
LEAVES MORE QUESTIONS THAT NEED
TO BE ANSWERED.
OBVIOUSLY, HE PROBABLY CARRIED
THE PISTOLS BECAUSE THEY'RE MORE
EASILY CONCEALED.
THAT MADE IT EASIER FOR HIM TO
APPROACH THE SCHOOL.
IF HE WAS WALKING UP TO THE
SCHOOL WITH A RIVAL, THEY COULD
HAVE OBVIOUSLY LOCKED DOWN,
CALLED THE POLICE.
HE MAY HAVE LEFT THAT THE RIFLE
IN THE VEHICLE AS A BACKUP.
>> SO THERE ARE OTHER RIFLES,
THREE OTHERS, AND IT'S REALLY
THE FIRST TIME THAT WE'VE HEARD
ABOUT THESE OTHER THREE.
ONE IS CALLED A HENRY REPEATING
RIFLE.
WHAT IS THAT?
>> THE OTHER THREE RIFLES THAT
WERE DESCRIBED EARLIER ARE
MAINLY HUNTING TYPE RIFLES.
THEY'RE NOT TYPICALLY CALLED AN
ASSAULT TYPE RIFLE.
MUCH LIKE THE BUSHMASTER IS.
>> SO WE HAVE BEEN TOLD AND IT'S
NOT A LOT OF INFORMATION, BUT
THERE IS SOME INDICATIONING THAT
THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER MIGHT
EARLIER IN THE WEEK ON TUESDAY
HAVE GONE TO PURCHASE A GUN AT A
LOCAL STORE.
IT'S UNCLEAR WHAT HAPPENED.
IF HE -- IF THERE WAS A WAITING
PERIOD AS WE KNOW WHAT HAPPENS
HERE IN CONNECTICUT OR WHAT
EXACTLY STOPPED HIM.
HE'S 20 YEARS OLD.
NO CRIMINAL RECORD.
WOULD HE HAVE BEEN ABLE TO JUST
GOEN AN PURCHASE A GUN IN THIS
STATE?
>> AT 20 YEARS OLD, HE COULD
PURCHASE A LONG GUN.
OBVIOUSLY YOU NEED TO BE 21 TO
PURCHASE A HANDGUN FROM A GUN
DEALER.
HOWEVER, COULD YOU PURCHASE ONE
ON THE STREET.
OBVIOUSLY BETWEEN INDIVIDUALS.
BUT IN ORDER TO GO INTO A GUN
STORE LICENSED DEALER, YOU
COULD -- YOU HAVE TO BE 1 YEARS
OLD TO BUY A LONG GUN, WHICH
MOST SPORTING GOODS STORES ONLY
SELL HUNTING TYPE RIFLES.
>> SO WE KNOW THAT THEY HAVE
CONTINUED TO SEAL OFF THE
SCHOOL, AND EARLIER IN A PRESS
CONFERENCE, WE HEARD FROM THE
STATE POLICE THAT IT'S AN ACTIVE
CRIME SCENE AND THAT THEY'RE
GOING TO GO INTO EVERY CREVICE
AND CORNER.
WHAT ARE THEY SEARCHING FOR AT
THIS POINT?
>> OBVIOUSLY THEY'RE GOING TO
LOOK TO RECOVER ALL THE FIRED
BULLETS.
WHETHER THEY -- IF THEY MISS,
WENT INTO WALLS AND CEILING
CANS, ET CETERA, THEY'LL RECOVER
SO THEY CAN GET A GOOD ESTIMATE
AS TO HOW MANY SHOTS WERE FIRED.
IF THEY FIND ANY DIFFERENT TYPE
OF CALIBER, OBVIOUSLY, THEY'D
LIKE TO KNOW THAT.
THEY HAVE TO VERIFY THAT THIS
WAS THE ONLY SHOOTER WHICH I
THINK THEY'VE ALREADY DONE AND
THAT ALL THE WEAPONS THAT WERE
USED HAVE BEEN RECOVERED.
SO THEY'LL BE DOING THIS CRIME
SCENE AS WELL AS GOING -- THE
SHOOTER COULD HAVE COME INTO THE
SCHOOL DAYS BEFORE, COULD HAVE
SECRETE THINGS MUCH LIKE THEY
DID IN COLUMBINE WHERE THEY
COULD HAVE PUT OTHER DEVICES.
THEY NEED TO MAKE SURE BY THE
TIME THEY LEAVE THIS SCHOOL,
EVERYTHING THAT NEEDS TO BE DONE
IN THIS CRIME SCENE HAS BEEN
COMPLETED AND THEY CAN TURN IT
BACK OVER TO THE SCHOOL
OFFICIALS.
>> AND AS WE START THE BY SAYING
MORE QUESTIONS THAN ANSWERS AND
MAYBE THERE WILL NEVER BE ALL
THE ANSWERS THAT WE NEED TO KNOW
IN THIS CASE.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR EXPERTISE ON
THE WEAPONRY.
I APPRECIATE IT.
A LITTLE BIT EARLIER, WOLF
BLITZER SPOKE WITH OUR CHIEF
MEDICAL CORRESPONDENT SANJAY
GUPTA.
THEY WERE TALKING ABOUT THE
SUPPORT THAT IS AVAILABLE FOR
THOSE WHO HAVE BEEN ACHED BY THE
TRAGEDY.
LET'S LISTEN IN.
>> YOU JUST CAME BACK FROM A
CRISIS CENTER HERE.
TELL US WHAT WAS GOING ON.
>> IT WAS UNCLEAR HOW MANY
PEOPLE WERE USING THE CENTER,
AND I CAN TELL YOU AT THIS
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL JUST ABOUT A
MILE FROM HERE, THIS CRISIS CITY
IS SET UP BY DANBURY HOSPITAL,
THE SAME HOSPITAL THAT TOOK CARE
OF A COUPLE OF PEOPLE WOUNDED
INITIALLY IN THE SHOOTING
YESTERDAY.
SAME HOSPITAL SETTING UP THIS
CRISIS CENTER.
THERE WERE PROBABLY ABOUT 100
CARS IN THE PARKING LOT.
OBVIOUSLY THE RESPECT FOR
PRIVACY, WE DIDN'T FILM THEM.
BUT FAMILIES COMING IN, SMALL
CHILDREN, SOME SINGLE MOMS AND
DADS AND ENTIRE FAMILIES, AS
WELL.
THEY WERE ALSO STAYING FOR A
LONG TIME.
THIS WASN'T ONE OF THOSE THINGS
WHERE PEOPLE WERE COMING IN AND
OUT CONSTANTLY.
THE WHOLE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL I
GUESS SORT OF DEDICATED TO THIS
TODAY FOR 12 HOURS.
AS YOU KNOW, WOLF, YALE NEW
HANCH WHICH HAS A NATIONALLY
RENOWNED-CRISIS CENTER.
>> YALE UNIVERSITY.
>> IN NEW HAVEN, THEY'VE DONE
CRISIS COUNSELING ALL OVER THE
COUNTRY.
OBVIOUSLY, THEY'RE NOT TOO FAR
FROM HERE BUT THEY ALSO HAVE A
PHONE LINE SET UP AND PEOPLE
HAVE BEEN CALLING IN CONSTANTLY
FROM THIS AREA BUT FROM ALL OVER
THE PLACE.
THIS HAS BEEN SOMETHING THAT
WE'RE HEARING PEOPLE ALL OVER
THE COUNTRY HAVE BEEN AFFECTED
BY AND USING SOME OF THESE
RESOURCES.
>> SO THEY'RE BRINGING A
PSYCHIATRIST, PSYCHOLOGISTS BUT
OTHER MEDICAL PROFESSIONALS AS
WELL?
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
AND PARTICULARLY CHILD
COUNSELORS.
YOU KNOW, THE PEOPLE WHO
SPECIALIZENY DEALING WITH
CHILDREN.
THEY HAVE PSYCHOLOGISTS AND
PSYCHIATRISTS AND THE
PSYCHIATRISTS CAN OBVIOUSLY
BEING PEOPLE MEDICAL DOCTORS.
THEY CAN PRESCRIBE MEDICATIONS.
WE DON'T KNOW IF PRESCRIPTIONS
ARE BEING GIMP.
BUT A LOT OF COUNSELING CLEARLY
GOING ON.
PEOPLE ARE CLEARLY USING THESE
RESOURCES.
THEY DON'T WANT TO TALK
OBVIOUSLY IN THE PARKING LOT
ABOUT IT, BUT GHG QUITE
PRIVATELY.
YOU CAN TELL THERE'S A HUGE
DEMAND.
>> IF YOU'RE A MOM OR A DAD AND
YOU'VE SEEN WHAT'S GOING ON,
FORTUNATELY LET'S SAY YOUR KIDS
ARE OKAY, BUT YOU'RE STILL IN A
STATE OF SHOCK, WHAT KIND OF
MEDICAL TREATMENT?
THERE ARE PROBABLY SOME DRUGS
THAT YOU CAN GIVE BUT WHAT DO
YOU DO?
>> YOU KNOW, ONE OF THE THINGS
THAT I THINK AND YOU AND I BOTH
COVERED A LOT OF THESE.
FOR PARENTS ESPECIALLY REALLY
ALMOST CHECKING THEIR OWN
FEELINGS FIRST, MAKING SURE THEY
HAVE THEIR OWN FEELINGS IN
CONTROL.
IT'S BEEN HARD FOR ME FOR YOU
I'M SURE AS WELL BEFORE TALKING
TO YOUR KIDS TO MAKE SURE YOU
HAVE SOME CONTROL OF YOUR
FEELINGS AND THEN BEING AS
TRANSPARENT AS POSSIBLE ABOUT
THIS.
ONE OF THE TECHNIQUES THAT SEEMS
TO MAKE A DIFFERENCE AND I KEEP
HEARING THIS FROM EXPERTS IN THE
FIELD IS LET THE CHILD IN THIS
CASE DO THE TALKING FIRST.
GET AN IDEA OF HOW MUCH THEY
KNOW AND THEN SLOWLY FILL IN
DETAILS BUT NOT TOO GRAPHIC
DETAILS OBVIOUSLY.
AGAIN THIS WHOLE SIMPLISTIC
NOTION OF RE-ESTABLISHING A
ROUTINE.
IT SOUNDS ALMOST TOO SIMPLE IN A
SITUATION LIKE THIS TOO SMALL.
BUT IT CAN MAKE A BIG
DIFFERENCE.
IT'S AROUND THE HOLIDAYS.
PEOPLE MAIL VIF HOLIDAY
ACTIVITIES, SOCCER PRACTICE,
THINGS LIKE THAT, GETTING BACK
INTO THAT GROOVE.
THEY FIND IF YOU CAN ESTABLISH
THAT SOONER RATHER THAN LATER,
YOU'RE MUCH MORE LIKELY TO
REALLY MITIGATE SOME OF THESE
SYMPTOMS.
IF I WAS LOOKING AT SOME OF THE
DATA, FOR EXAMPLE, VIRGINIA
TECH.
EVEN ABOUT THREE TO FOUR MONTHS
AFTERWARD, ABOUT 15% OF PEOPLE
STILL HAD SIGNIFICANT PTSD.
IF PEOPLE ACTUALLY SAUL SOME OF
THE VIOLENCE, IT WENT UP TO AS
HIGH AS 77%.
YOU TYPICALLY THINK OF IT AS
SOMETHING YOU SEE IN ADULTS BUT
YOU SEE IT IN CHILDREN, AS WELL.
WE'RE GETTING MORE AND MORE
EVIDENCE OF THAT ALL THE TIME.
>> DR. SANJAY GUPTA AND WOLF
BLITZER ARE TALKING WHAT PEOPLE
CAN DO TO TRY TO GIVE SOME
SOLACE TO THEIR CHILDREN IN THE
WAKE OF SUCH A TERRIBLE TRAGEDY.
GOING TO TAKE A SHORT BREAK.
WHEN WE COME BACK, WE'LL
CONTINUE TO UPDATE YOU ON THE
VERY LATEST ON THE ALLEGED
SHOOTER IN THIS CASE.
WHAT'S HAPPENING HERE IN TOWN AS
PEOPLE COME TOGETHER TO TRY TO
SHOW SUPPORT FOR THOSE WHO HAVE
LOST EVERYTHING HERE.
AND ALSO, WE'LL UPDATE YOU ON
THE INVESTIGATION AS WE CONTINUE
TO GET INFORMATION FROM LAW
ENFORCEMENT SOURCES.
THAT'S AHEAD.
WE'RE BACK IN JUST A MOMENT.
>> IT'S HORRIFIC.
IT'S JUST YOU FEEL THE PAIN OF
THESE PEOPLE.
THE CHILDREN, THE YOUNG
CHILDREN.
I LOST MY CHILD, AND IT LEAVES A
SCAR.
IT DOESN'T GO AWAY.
IT'S A HORRIBLE THING BECAUSE
YOU FEEL HELPLESS.
YOU FEEL LIKE YOU WANT TO DO
SOMETHING, BUT WHAT DO YOU DO?
YOU PRAY.
OUR FAMILY GOT TOGETHER LAST
TIME WE PRAYED.
AND MY WIFE AND I, AND THE
EDUCATORS AND THE ADMINISTRATORS
THAT LOST THEIR LIVES AND THEY
HAVE FAMILIES ALSO.
YOU KNOW?
AND CHILDREN.
AND SO IT'S IMPACTED THE TOWN,
IT'S
IT'S IMPACTED THE STATE, THE
WORLD, THE U.S.
IT'S A HORRIBLE THING.
SantHo, Ho, Ho!anta!
Santa!
Want to see some magic?
Watch this! Merry Chr...
(Crash) Ow!
I landed on my keys.
Did you get that?
Oh yeah.
That was amazing.
Here you go.
That was a fun trick!
See? Santa's okay.
Walk it off Santa.
Share videos instantly
with S Beam.
On the Galaxy SIII
and Note II.
For a limited time get two flip
covers for the price of one.
Exclusively at Verizon.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] WHILE YOU'RE
GETTING READY FOR THE HOLIDAYS,
WE'RE GETTING READY FOR YOU.
TIS THE SEASON.
FOR FOOD, FOR FAMILY,
AND NOW, SOMETHING EXTRA --
FOR YOU.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
IT IS NOT AN EXAGGERATION TO SAY
THAT THE WORLD IS MOURNING TODAY
AFTER THE TRAGEDY THAT HAS TAKEN
PLACE AT A CONNECTICUT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL TO KNOW THAT
CHILDREN AS YOUNG AS 5 YEARS OLD
HAD TO WITNESS A GUNMAN SHOOTING
AND KILLING THEIR CLASSMATES AND
TEACHERS AND PRINCIPALS.
HEART BREAKING.
KATE BOLDUAN SPOKE TO THE MOTHER
OF A FIRST GRADER WHO WITNESSED
DWLAEDS MASSACRE RIGHT OUTSIDE
HIS CLASSROOM.
TELL ME A LITTLE BIT ABOUT WHAT
THE MOTHER TOLD YOU.
>> I SPOKE WITH THE MOTHER AND
THE FATHER.
THEY'RE ACTUALLY PARENTS OF TWO
CHILDREN AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
THEIR SON IS 6 YEARS OLD AND IN
FIRST GRADE.
THEIR DAUGHTER 7 YEARS OLD IN
SECOND GRADE, IF YOU CAN BELIEVE
IT.
THEY TOLD A HARROWING STORY OF
HOW IT ALL UNFOLDED BEFORE THEIR
SON'S EYES.
THEY SAID THAT THEY HAD HEARD
HAMMERS FALLING IS WHAT ALL THE
KIDS THOUGHT.
WHEN THEY LEARNED IT WAS
GUNSHOTS, THEIR TEACHER VICKI
SOTO MOVED THEM AS FAR AS AWAY
FROM THE DOOR AS POSSIBLE.
THAT IS WHEN THE GUNMAN BURST IN
AND SHOT VICKI SOTO BEFORE THEIR
EYES.
SOMEHOW IN A MIRACULOUS TWIST,
THEIR SON AIDEN AND SEVERAL KIDS
WERE ABLE TO, HAD THE PRESENCE
OF MIND TO SOMEHOW RUN OUT, RUN
DIRECTLY PAST THE GUNMAN WHO WAS
STANDING IN THE DOORWAY,
DIRECTLY PAST THE GUNMAN INTO
THE HALLWAY OUT OF THE SCHOOL
DOWN THE ROAD.
EVENTUALLY TO SAFETY.
NOW, I'VE BEEN TOLD A FAMILY
MEMBER HAS TOLD SOME OF OUR
LOCAL AFFILIATES THAT VICKI SOTO
IS DEAD.
SHE WAS FEARED DEAD FOR QUITE A
LONG TIME.
LAW ENFORCEMENT SOURCE HAS TOLD
US SHE IS AMONG THE DEAD NOW AND
SHE DIED SHIELDING HER STUDENTS
AS THEY SAID THAT SHE WAS A
WONDERFUL TEACHER AND THEY LOVED
HER SO MUCH.
I ASKED THE PARENTS, DIANE AND
ROBERT IF IT'S REGISTERED WITH
THEIR SON REALLY HOW THIS HAS
ALWAYS TRANSPIRED.
I THINK WE HAVE THAT SOUND BITE.
>> HE'S REASSURING HIMSELF THAT
SHE'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
HE REALLY, REALLY REALLY CARED
ABOUT HIS TEACHER.
HE WAS VERY CLOSE WITH HER AND
SHE REALLY LOVED THAT CLASS, AND
HE KEEPS SAYING I REALLY HOPE
SHE'S OKAY.
I HOPE IT'S NOT HER.
HE KNOWS THAT SHE'S BEEN HURT,
BUT HE DOESN'T NOTE END RESULT.
HE KNOWS THE KIDS THAT HE SAW
GETTING SHOT.
HE DOESN'T KNOW THE OUTCOME.
SO I THINK HE'S REASSURING
HIMSELF IN HIS OF-YEAR-OLD MIND.
I KNOW HE'S PROCESSING IT, BUT I
THINK HE'S REASSURING HIMSELF
AND TELLING HIMSELF THAT IT'S
GOING TO BE OKAY.
>> THEY ARE OBVIOUSLY
DISTRAUGHT.
TERRIBLE NEWS ABOUT VICKI SOTO
WHO HAS NOW BEEN CONFIRMED AS
KILLED, ONE OF THE NAMES THAT
THEY HAVE CONFIRMED.
THE FAMILY MEMBERS CONFIRMING.
WHAT WILL THEY DO WITH THEIR
CHILDREN?
I MEAN THE TRAUMA THAT THEY'VE
EXPERIENCED, I DON'T KNOW HOW
THEY GET OVER THAT.
>> THEY WERE VERY CANDID AND
SAID THEY DON'T KNOW.
THIS IS NOT SOMETHING YOU
EXPECT.
THIS NEVER HAPPENS IN YOUR TOWN.
THIS DEFINITELY HAPPENS IN YOUR
CHILDREN'S SCHOOL.
AND DEFINITELY NEVER HAPPENS IN
YOUR CHILDREN'S CLASSROOM.
AND THEY SAY THIS IS NOT -- THIS
IS SOMETHING THAT THIS TOWN WILL
NEVER BE THE SAME AFTER.
I THINK THAT'S UNDERSTANDABLE.
THEY'RE TRYING TO LET THEIR SON
AND DAUGHTER KIND OF LEAD THE
WAY.
THEY'RE JUST TRYING TO SPEND A
LOT OF TIME TOGETHER.
THEY ALL SLEPT IN THE SAME BED
LAST NIGHT IN ORDER TO ENJOY THE
TIME.
IT'S AN UNBELIEVABLE BLESSING,
AN UNDERSTATEMENT THAT THEY ARE
ALL TOGETHER AND THE RELIEF THEY
FELT WHEN THEY WERE ABLE TO FIND
THEIR TWO CHILDREN.
SHE SAID WAS INDESCRIBABLE.
AT THE VERY SAME TIME, THEY
UNDERSTAND THERE ARE SO MANY
FAMILIES THAT CANNOT SHARE THAT
KIND OF RELIEF TODAY.
THIS IS WHY THEY WANTED TO SPEAK
OUT BECAUSE THEY WANT TO TRY TO
HELP TELL THE STORIES OF THOSE
THAT HAVE BEEN LOST AND ALSO TO
TRY TO HELP THIS COMMUNITY
SLOWLY SOMEHOW BEGIN TO HEAL
AFTER THIS HORRIFIC TRAGEDY.
>> IF HER SON RAFT PAST THE
GUNMAN, IT WAS THAT CLASSROOM
ONE OF THE TWO SHOT UP.
MANY OF THOSE KILLED WERE IN
THAT CLASSROOM HER SON'S
CLASSMATES.
>> THEIR SON AIDEN AND ROBERT
WAS THE FATHER WAS WITH THE SON
WHEN HE WAS SPEAKING TO
DETECTIVES.
THEY SAID -- THEY WERE VERY
PROUD OF THE AMOUNT OF DETAIL IN
THIS 6-YEAR-OLD BOY COULD
REMEMBER HOW THIS UNFOLDED.
HE SAID HE SAW THE GUNMAN.
HE SAW HIM SHOOT HIS TEACHER AND
HE ALSO HAD MENTIONED THAT HE
HAD SEEN OTHER KIDS GETTING
SHOT.
HE HAD NOT GONE INTO DETAIL OF
HOW, WHERE, WHEN OR YOU KNOW,
HOW IT ALL UNFOLDED IN WHAT WAY.
IT'S UNBELIEVABLE TO ME AND I'M
SURE TO YOU WITH CHILDREN TO
THINK AT THAT MOMENT THAT THESE
CHILDREN HAVE THE PRESENCE OF
MIND TO RUN AND FLEE RATHER THAN
BE FROZEN IN FEAR AND MAKE IT TO
SAFETY.
IT'S ONLY BECAUSE THERE WERE
ANGELS IN THE ROOM THAT DAY.
THERE'S NO OTHER WAY TO EXPLAIN
IT.
>> AND SO MANY OTHERS DIDN'T
MAKE IT OUT.
THE TEACHERS HAVE REALLY EMERGED
AS THE TRUE HEROES IN THE STORY.
THE NUMBER OF TEACHERS WHO
LITERALLY HAVE THROWN THEMSELVES
IN FRONT OF CHILDREN TO TRY TO
PROTECT THEM FROM GUNFIRE IS
STUNNING.
>> VICKI SOTO IS A YOUNG WOMAN.
SHE IS SOME 27 YEARS OLD.
A YOUNG, YOUNG WOMAN AND TO
THINK IN THAT MOMENT OF TERROR,
THAT'S WHAT THEY DO TO PROTECT
THESE CHILDREN, IT'S AMAZING.
>> OUR HEARTS BREAK FOR ALL THE
FAMILIES TODAY.
KATE, THANK YOU FOR THAT REPORT.
APPRECIATE IT.
AS EACH HOUR GOES BY, THERE'S
MORE INFORMATION THAT TRICKLES
OUT OR WE GET CLARIFICATION ON
SOME OF THE INFORMATION THAT WAS
CONTRADICTORY INCLUDING ABOUT
THE WEAPONS USED TO KILL ALL
THOSE PEOPLE YESTERDAY.
POLICE SAY THE SUSPECT HAD
ACCESS TO SIX GUNS.
WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE
PRINCIPAL OF THE SCHOOL, THE
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST, A TEACHER
IN THE SCHOOL, WANT TO GET TO
NATIONAL CORRESPONDENT SUSAN
CANDIOTTI.
SORRY SUSAN FOR MANNING LING
THAT.
OBVIOUSLY YOU AND I TALKING FOR
MANY HOURS OVER THE LAST 24
HOURS.
YOU WERE ONE OF THE FIRST
REPORTERS ON THE SCENE
YESTERDAY.
I KNOW THE INFORMATION COMES OUT
A LITTLE BIT AT A TIME.
LET'S START WITH THE GUNS.
WHAT INFORMATION IS NEW ABOUT
THE WEAPONS USED?
>> WELL, BIG PICTUREWISE,
REMEMBER AT THIS MORNING'S NEWS
CONFERENCE, THE STATE POLICE
SAID THAT A BETTER PICTURE WAS
EMERGING FROM THEM ABOUT WHAT
LED TO THIS.
PART OF THAT HAS TO DO WITH
GUNS.
SO THE NEW INFORMATION THAT
WE'RE REPORTING NOW AS I JUST
CAME BACK FROM DICK'S SPORTING
GOODS HERE IN DANBURY,
CONNECTICUT, NEARBY HERE, AND I
WAS ABLE TO LEARN FROM LAW
ENFORCEMENT SOURCES THAT IN THE
DAYS BEFORE LITERALLY TUESDAY OF
THIS WEEK, THAT THE SUSPECTED
SHOOTER IN THIS CASE, ADAM
LANZA, WENT TO THE STORE AND
TRIED TO BUY A GUN.
HE WASN'T SUCCESSFUL.
WE DO NOT KNOW EXACTLY WHAT KIND
OF A GUN THAT HE WAS TRYING TO
BUY, BUT OUR SOURCES SAY THAT
FOR WHATEVER REASON, HE JUST
DIDN'T WANT TO WAIT AROUND AND
WASN'T INTERESTED AND LEFT.
HOWEVER, I'VE ALSO LEARNED THAT
STORE EMPLOYEES ARE COOPERATING
WITH INVESTIGATORS ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED, AND THAT THEY ARE
CURRENTLY SEARCHING THEIR STORE
SURVEILLANCE CAMERAS FOR VIDEO
THAT WOULD INDICATE THAT THE
SUSPECTED SHOOTER WAS, IN FACT,
IN THAT STORE ON TUESDAY TO TRY
TO FIRM THAT UP.
ALSO WE'VE LEARNED AND YOU'VE
POINTED OUT THAT THE SUSPECTED
SHOOTER IN THIS CASE HAD ACCESS
TO AT LEAST SIX GUNS, MAY HAVE
HAD ACCESS TO AS MANY AS SIX
GUNS.
HE CERTAINLY HAD ACCESS 0 THREE
OF THEM, AND AUTHORITIES NOW
TELL US, OUR SOURCES, THAT THE
THREE GUNS THAT WE'VE BEEN
TELLING YOU ABOUT SINCE
YESTERDAY, THAT IS THE GLOCK,
THE SIG SAUER AND THE BUSHMASTER
THAT ORIGINALLY WAS THOUGHT TO
BE IN THE MOTHER'S CAR OUTSIDE
WERE ACTUALLY ALL THREE WERE
FOUND WITH HIM IN THE CLASSROOM.
AND ALSO AUTHORITIES SAY THEY DO
KNOW WHICH OF THOSE THREE GUNS
HE USED TO KILL HIMSELF BUT
THEY'RE NOT REVEALING THAT AT
THIS TIME.
NOW, SPEAKING TO THE ISSUE OF
ACCESS, WE ALSO KNOW THAT IN
THAT VEHICLE OUTSIDE, IT IS
STILL UNCLEAR WHETHER YET
ANOTHER VEHICLE WHICH MIGHT MEAN
A SEVENTH ONE MIGHT HAVE BEEN IN
THAT CAR.
WE JUST DON'T KNOW THE ANSWER TO
THAT YET.
NOW, WE KNOW THAT THOSE THREE
OTHER WEAPONS, SOLEDAD, THAT
WE'VE REFERRED TO ARE THREE
RIFLES THAT HE MAY HAVE HAD
ACCESS TO.
HOWEVER THEY'RE DESCRIBED TO US
AS SORT OF LONG GUNS OR
CERTAINLY OLDER MODELS THAT
MIGHT POSSIBLY HAVE BEEN PART OF
A GUN COLLECTION AND THEREFORE,
MIGHT NOT HAVE HAD INTEREST TO
THE SHOOTER TO BE USED IN THIS
CASE.
WE HAVE ALSO LEARNED FROM CNN'S
DAVID ARIOSTO, HE SPOKE WITH A
MAN WHO OWNS A LANDSCAPING
BUSINESS AND SAID VERY RECENTLY
THAT THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER SHOWED
HIM A NEW GUN PURCHASE SHE HAD
MADE AND SAID IT WAS PART OF A
GUN COLLECTION AND SHE ALSO TOLD
HIM THAT SHE WOULD OFTEN GO
TARGET SHOOTING.
>> TOWN OF NEWTOWN PAT LAGORA.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON, EVERYONE.
I HAVE COMMENTS ON THE BAFFLE OF
THE TOWN GOVERNMENT AND THE
SUPERINTENDENT OF SCHOOLS WHO
WAS UNABLE TO BE WITH US TODAY.
NEWTOWN HAS SUFFERED A
HORRENDOUS TRAGEDY.
A HARM THAT HAS BROKEN OUR
HEARTS.
OUR WOUND IS DEEP BECAUSE WE ARE
A CLOSE KNIT COMMUNITY.
WE TRULY CARE FOR EACH OTHER.
WE ARE COMING TOGETHER WITH LOVE
AND SUPPORT FOR THOSE FAMILIES
WHO HAVE SUFFERED THIS TERRIBLE
LOSS.
WE ARE A STRONG AND CARING
PLACE.
WE WILL PUT OUR ARMS AROUND
THOSE FAMILIES AND AROUND EACH
OTHER.
WE WILL FIND A WAY TO HEAL SO
THAT ALL OF OUR RESIDENTS, YOUNG
AND OLD, WILL AGAIN FIND PEACE.
I ASK THAT YOU HELP US IN THIS
HEALING PROCESS.
PLEASE TREAT OUR COMMUNITY WITH
KINDNESS.
PLEASE KNOW THAT WE HAVE
SUFFERED A TERRIBLE LOSS AND WE
NEED YOUR RESPECT ON THIS
HEALING JOURNEY.
I TURN TO YOU AS PARENTS, AS
SIBLINGS, AS CARING PEOPLE TO
KNOW THAT YOUR WORDS AND YOUR
ACTIONS CAN HELP US ON THIS
HEALING JOURNEY OR YOU CAN
HINDER US.
I WANT TO TAKE A MOMENT TOO TO
THANK ALL THE SUPPORT THAT WE'VE
RECEIVED FROM THE GOVERNOR'S
OFFICE, FROM THE STATE POLICE,
FROM MANY CLINICIANS AND CLERGY,
FROM THE OUTREACH ACROSS THE
NATION, AND ACROSS THE WORLD.
I THINK WE WERE ALL TOUCHED BY
THE MAGNITUDE OF THIS TRAGEDY.
SO I THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
LISTENING TO MY MESSAGE.
AND I HOPE YOU TAKE MY COMMENTS
TO HEART.
THANK YOU.
>> PLEASE SPELL YOUR NAME SLOWLY
FOR US.
>> MY NAME IS SPELLED
L-L-O-D-R-A-PRONOUNCED LOAD-RA.
I AM THE FIRST SELECTMAN OF THIS
COMMUNITY.
>> IS THAT YOUR FIRST AND YOUR
LAST NAME.
>> MY FIRST NAME IS PATRICIA.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> THE SECOND GENTLEMAN THAT IS
HERE TODAY HIS TEAM HAS BEEN
WORKING VERY, VERY HARD WITH THE
IDENTIFICATION AND THE POST MORT
TERM EXAMINATION.
THE STATE OF CONNECTICUT CHIEF
STATE MEDICAL EXAMINER DR. H.
WAYNE CARVER.
>> THANK YOU, PAUL.
FIRST OF ALL, ON BEHALF OF MY
WIFE AND MY SONS, AND ON BEHALF
OF MY OTHER FAMILY, OUR PEOPLE
AT THE OFFICE, CHIEF MEDICAL
EXAMINER, WE WISH TO EXTEND OUR
DEEPEST SYMPATHIES TO THE
FAMILIES AND EVERYONE ELSE WHO
HAS BEEN SO HURT BY THIS EVENT.
OF OUR THOUGHTS AND OUR PRAYERS
ARE WITH YOU.
THE OFFICE OF THE CHIEF MEDICAL
EXAMINER GOT HERE, ACTUALLY THE
CHIEF MEDICAL EXAMINER GOT HERE
A COUPLE HOURS AFTER THE
BUILDING WAS SECURED.
WE WERE HERE UNTIL APPROXIMATELY
12:30 LAST NIGHT.
WE THANK THE EMERGENCY SERVICES
WHO BUILT US A TEMPORARY
FACILITY IN THE PARKING LOT.
AND WE TOOK IDENTIFICATION,
PHOTOGRAPHS AND DID PRELIMINARY
IDENTIFICATION ON ALL THE
VICTIMS.
AND HAD EVERYBODY TRANSPORTED
BACK TO FARMINGTON BY ABOUT 1:00
IN THE MORNING.
OUR ENTIRE STAFF TURNED OUT.
STARTED THE POSTMORTEM
EXAMINATIONS THIS MORNING.
WE'VE COMPLETED THE CHILDREN BY
ABOUT 1:30.
AND I BELIEVE EVERYBODY EXCEPT
THE ASSAILANT AND HIS MOTHER
WILL BE FINISHED TONIGHT.
AND I'LL DO THOSE TOMORROW
MORNING.
LIEUTENANT VANCE AND STAFF HAVE
A LIST OF THE NAMES AND THE
DATES OF BIRTH.
ANYTHING ELSE?
NO, NO.
AND THAT WILL BE DISTRIBUTED.
HOPE YOU'VE GOT ENOUGH COPIES.
EVERYBODY, DEATH WAS CAUSED
BY -- EVERY ONE THAT WE'VE
COMPLETED SO FAR WAS CAUSED BY
GUNSHOT WOUNDS.
AND OBVIOUSLY, THE MANNER OF
DEATH ON ALL OF THESE CASES HAS
BEEN CLASSIFIED AS HOMICIDE.
>> HOW MANY MEDICAL EXAMINERS
WORKED WITH YOU TODAY, SIR?
>> I HAVE FOUR DOCTORS AND MAN.
I THINK ALL TEN OF MY
TECHNICIANS BOTH THE FULL-TIMERS
AND PART-TIMERS WERE THERE.
AND ONE STUDENT FROM QUINNIPIAC
UNIVERSITY, THIS WAS HER FIRST
DAY.
THAT WAS KIND OF INTERESTING.
AND THE MAJORITY OF OUR
INVESTIGATIVE STAFF WERE WORKING
ON THIS AT SOME POINT.
WHETHER THEY WERE WITH US LAST
NIGHT OR ON THE JOB TODAY.
AND OUR -- I THINK A LOT OF OUR
CHAIR CAL OR WHAT THEY CALL
PROCESSING TECHS WHO DO THE
PAPERWORK AND SO FORTH WERE
THERE.
THEY'RE UP ALL ON THE SECOND
FLOOR AND I DIDN'T GET THERE
TODAY.
>> SIR, YOU OBVIOUSLY BY THE
NATURE OF YOUR JOB, YOU DEAL
WITH HORRIBLE THINGS AT TIMES.
IS THIS ONE OVER THE TOP?
IS THIS ONE A BIT DIFFERENT THAN
ANYTHING YOU'VE DONE BEFORE,
SIR?
>> DID EVERYBODY HEAR THE
QUESTION?
>> NO.
>> IT WAS GIVEN WHAT I DEAL WITH
ALL THE TIME, IS THIS ONE OVER
THE TOP.
I'VE BEEN AT THIS FOR A THIRD OF
A CENTURY.
AND IT'S MY SENSIBILITIES MAY
NOT BE THE AVERAGE MAN.
BUT THIS PROBABLY IS THE WORST I
HAVE SEEN OR THE WORST THAT I
KNOW OF ANY OF MY COLLEAGUES
HAVING SEEN.
AND THAT ALL THE MORE MAKES ME
PROUD AND GRATEFUL TO OUR STAFF
WHO TO A MAN HAVE JUST BEHAVED
MOST PROFESSIONALLY AND STRONGLY
AND I HOPE THEY AND I HOPE THE
PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN DON'T HAVE IT
CRASH ON THEIR HEAD LATER ABOUT
YOU,.
>> Reporter: DOCTOR, ON THAT
EXAMINATION, COULD YOU TELL
WHICH CALIBER OF THE HANDGUN
COMPARED TO THE RIFLE OF THESE
SHOOTING VICTIMS WERE?
>> IT'S A GOOD THING IT'S NOT A
PROSECUTION BECAUSE THEN I
COULDN'T ANSWER YOU THAT.
ALL OF THE WOUNDS I KNOW OF AT
THIS POINT WERE CAUSED BY THE
LONG WEAPON.
>> SO THE RIFLE WAS THE THE
PRIMARY WEAPON.
>> YES.
>> WHAT CALIBER WERE THE --
>> THE QUESTION WAS WHAT CALIBER
WERE THESE BULLETS.
I KNOW, I PROBABLY KNOW MORE
ABOUT FIREARMS THAN MOST
PATHOLOGISTS BUT IF I SAY IT IN
COURT THEY YELL AT ME AND DON'T
MAKE ME ANSWER.
SO I'LL LET THE POLICE DEAL WITH
THAT FOR YOU.
>> DOCTOR, CAN YOU TELL ABOUT
THE NATURE OF THE WOUNDS?
WERE THEY AT VERY CLOSE RANGE?
WERE THE CHILDREN SHOT FROM
ACROSS THE ROOM?
>> I ONLY DID SEVEN OF THE
AUTOPSIES.
THE VICTIMS I HAD RANGED FROM 3
TO 11 WOUNDS APIECE.
I ONLY SAW TWO OF THEM WITH
CLOSE RANGE SHOOTING.
BUT THAT'S A SAMPLE.
I REALLY DON'T HAVE OF DETAILED
INFORMATION ON THE REST OF THE
INJURIES.
>> BUT YOU SAID IT WAS THE LONG
RIFLE THAT WAS USED?
>> YES.
>> I THOUGHT THE LONG RIFLE WAS
DISCOVERED IN THE CAR.
THAT'S NOT CORRECT?
>> THAT'S NOT CORRECT, SIR.
>> HOW MANY BULLETS CASINGS DID
YOU FIND TOTAL?
>> OH.
I'M LUCKY I CAN TELL YOU HOW
MANY I FOUND.
I DON'T KNOW.
THERE WERE LOTS OF THEM, OKAY?
THIS TYPE OF WEAPON IS NOT --
THE BULLETS ARE DESIGNED IN SUCH
A FASHION THAT THE ENERGY --
THIS IS VERY CLINICAL.
I SHOULDN'T BE SAYING THIS, BUT
THE ENERGY IS DEPOSITED IN THE
TISSUE AND SO THE BULLET STAYS
IN.
>> DOCTOR, DID THE CHILDREN DIE
QUICKLY?
>> THAT'S ALWAYS A DIFFICULT
QUESTION AND OBVIOUSLY I DON'T
HA
HAVE -- I DON'T HAVE DETAILED
INFORMATION ON ALL OF THEM, BUT
THIS IS A VERY DEVASTATING SET
OF INJURIES.
>> DID THEY SUFFER?
>> I DON'T -- I DON'T -- THE
BEST OF MY ABILITY TO ANSWER
THAT QUESTION WHICH IS ALWAYS
LESS THAN PERFECT, IF SO, NOT
FOR VERY LONG.
>> WERE MOST OF THE INJURIES
MULTIPLE?
>> ALL THE ONES -- I BELIEVE SO,
YES.
>> WHAT SHAPE ARE THE BODIES --
>> WE DID NOT BRING THE BODIES
AND THE FAMILIES INTO CONTACT.
WE TOOK PICTURES OF THEM.
OF THEIR FAISAL FEATURES.
YOU HAVE -- IT'S EASIER ON THE
FAMILIES WHEN YOU DO THAT.
THERE IS A TIME AND A PLACE FOR
UP CLOSE AND PERSONAL IN THE
GRIEVING PROCESS.
BUT TO ACCOMPLISH THIS WE FELT
IT WOULD BE BEST TO DO IT THIS
WAY AND YOU CAN SORT OF -- YOU
CAN CONTROL THE SITUATION
DEPENDING ON YOUR PHOTOGRAPHER.
I HAVE VERY GOOD PHOTOGRAPHERS.
ABOUT YOU.
>> DO YOU KNOW THE DIFFERENCE IN
THE TIME OF DEATH BETWEEN THE
BODY THAT WAS RECOVERED FROM THE
HOUSE AND THE BODIES THAT WERE
RECOVERED FROM THE SCHOOL?
>> NO, I DON'T.
>> HOW YOUNG.
>> SORRY, I DON'T.
>> HOW YOUNG WAS THE YOUNGEST
VICTIM, DOCTOR, HOW OLD WAS THE
OLDEST VICTIM.
>> YOU ALL HAVE TO LOOK AT THE
SPREAD SHEET WHEN WE PASS IT
OUT.
>> THAT YOU DEALT WITH.
>> ALL THE ONES I DEALT WITH --
EVERYBODY I DEALT WITH, I
BELIEVE THEY'RE ALL FIRST
GRADERS.
>> DID THE GUNMAN KILL HIMSELF
WITH THE RIFLE?
>> NO, I DON'T KNOW YET.
I'LL EXAMINE HIM TOMORROW
MORNING.
BUT I DON'T THINK SO.
>> WHAT ABOUT THE WOMAN IN THE
HOME?
>> HAVE I NOT SEEN HER YET.
>> THE CHILDREN ALL IN ONE
LOCATION, ONE CLASSROOM OR --
>> OKAY.
PAUL AND COMPANY WILL DEAL WITH
THAT.
PAUL AND COMPANY.
LIEUTENANT VANCE IS GOING TO
HANDLE THAT ONE.
>>.
>> Reporter: [ INAUDIBLE
QUESTION ].
>> WE DISCUSSED THIS BRIEFLY
WITH THE STAFF BEFORE I CAME
HERE.
THERE WAS OF -- I BELIEVE
EVERYBODY WAS HIT MORE THAN
ONCE.
>> WAS THERE ANY EVIDENCE OF A
STRUGGLE, ANY BRUISES OR --
>> THE NATURE OF THE SHOOTING
WAS THERE ANY SENSE THAT IT WAS
A LOT OF CARE TAKEN TO PRECISION
FROM THE SHOOTER OR WAS IT
SPREAD RANDOMLY?
>> BOTH.
IT'S VERY DIFFICULT QUESTION TO
ANSWER.
>> GIVEN THE WOUNDS?
>> YEAH.
IT'S REALLY -- YOU WOULD THINK
AFTER THE THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE
I'VE SEEN SHOT I COULD ANSWER
THAT QUESTION, BUT IT'S -- IF I
ATTEMPTED TO ANSWER IT IN COURT,
THERE WOULD BE AN ACTION AND
THEY WOULD WIN.
>> DOCTOR, CAN YOU DESCRIBE,
WHAT THE KIDS LOOKED LIKE WHEN
THEY CAME TO YOU, WHAT WERE THEY
WEARING?
>> THEY WERE WEARING CUTE KIDS'
STUFF.
THEY'RE FIRST GRADERS WEARING
CUTE KIDS STUFF.
YOU KNOW?
IT'S THE KIND OF STUFF YOU'D
ACCEPTED YOUR KIDS OR YOUR
GRANDKIDS OUT THE DOOR ON TO
FIRST GRADE IN.
>> DOCTOR, CAN WE DISCUSS THE
FATAL INJURIES TO THE ADULTS?
>> SIMILAR TO THOSE OF THE
CHILDREN.
>> DOCTOR, THE CHILDREN THAT YOU
AUTOPSIED, WHERE ON THE BODIES
WERE THOSE WOUNDS?
>> ALL OVER.
ALL OVER.
>> WHAT ABOUT THE MOTHER?
>> I HAVE NOT EXAMINED HER YET.
THAT WILL BE TOMORROW MORNING.
>> WERE THEY AT DECKS OR RUNNING
AWAY?
>> I'LL LET THE SCENE GUYS
ADDRESS THAT ISSUE.
OKAY?
OBVIOUSLY, I WAS AT THE SCENE.
OBVIOUSLY I'M VERY EXPERIENCED
IN THAT, BUT THERE ARE PEOPLE
WHO ARE THE NUMBER ONE
PROFESSIONALS ON THAT.
I'LL LET THEM HANDLE IT.
>> DOCTOR, YOU SAID THAT THE
BODIES THAT YOU EXAMINED, THE
SEVEN HAD THREE TO 11 SHOTS.
>> THAT'S JUST THE ONES THAT I
DID.
>> JUST THE ONES THAT YOU
EXAMINED.
SO THIS MAN WAS SHOOTING --
>> I THINK THE, YEAH, I THINK
THE GUY WHO'S DID THE CRIME
SCENE WILL BE ABLE TO TELL YOU
SOMETHING ABOUT HOW MANY CART
RIDGES WERE FOUND.
>> IS THIS PROTOCOL ON HOW YOU
DID THE AUNZS?
LIKE THE MOTHER AND THE.
>> OUR GOAL -- OUR GOAL WAS TO
GET THE KIDS OUT AND AVAILABLE
TO THE FUNERAL DIRECTORS FIRST.
JUST FOR -- WELL, OBVIOUS
REASONS.
>> HOW MANY BOYS, HOW MANY
GIRLS?
>> I HAVE NO IDEA.
>> DOCTOR.
>> I DON'T KNOW.
>> YOU SAID BEFORE WHEN I ASKED
YOU ABOUT, YOU SAID THIS IS THE
WORST YOU'VE SEEN.
I KNOW YOU'RE A PROFESSIONAL
AGAIN AND I KNOW YOU HAVE A
VENEER THAT YOU PUT UP.
WERE YOU EMOTIONAL AT ANY POINT?
DID THIS GET TO YOU AT ANY POINT
WHERE YOU HAD TO FIGHT BACK
TEARS?
>> NOT YET.
OKAY?
BUT YEAH, THERE HAVE BEEN TIMES
IN MY CAREER WHEN I'VE FOR
REASONS I DON'T APPRECIATE GO IN
THE LOCKER ROOM AND SIT DOWN AND
CRY, BUT -- AND I THINK IF
YOU -- IF YOU DON'T HAVE TO DO
THAT, YOU SHOULDN'T BE IN THIS
BUSINESS, BUT FOR THIS ONE, NOT
YET.
NOTICE I SAID YET.
ALL RIGHT, FOLKS.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> COULD YOU SAY AND SPELL YOUR
NAME.
>> YEAH, SURE.
I HOPE YOU ALL PUT THIS IN YOUR
CALENDAR BECAUSE IN 31 YEARS,
AND 26 AS CHIEF MEDICAL
EXAMINER, THIS IS ONLY THE
SECOND PRESS CONFERENCE I'VE
GIVEN.
IT'S H. WAYNE W-A-Y-N-E, CARVER,
C-A-AREN'T V-E-R, AND IT'S THE
SECOND.
THAT'S WHY I DON'T USE THE H.
BECAUSE WHEN MY FATHER ASKED MY
GRANDFATHER, HE SAID FINE, BUT
AS LONG AS YOU NEVER CALL HIM
HAROLD.
>> CAN YOU JUST REAL QUICKLY,
DID THEY SET UP A TENT IN THE
PARKING LOT?
>> IT WASN'T A TENT.
IT WAS THIS MAGNIFICENT THING.
AND IT'S SECTIONAL AND IT STICKS
TOGETHER WITH VELCRO AND THEN
THEY STAKE IT TO THE GROUND AND
ELECTRICITY AND LIGHTS APPEAR
FROM THE DEPARTMENT OF EMERGENCY
MANAGEMENT.
I THINK IT CAME FROM THE ARMY
BUT I'M NOT SURE.
I THINK IT'S THESE THINGS THAT
THEY USE IN TO SET UP FIELD
HOSPITALS VERY QUICKLY, MOBILE
HOSPITALS.
>> HAVE ALL OF THE CHILDREN'S
BODIES BEEN RETURNED TO THE
PATIENTS OR MORTUARIES?
>> I DON'T KNOW THE MORTUARIES
HAVE ALL BEEN CALLED.
>> BUT THEY'RE WAITING TO BE
RELEASED, THESE BODIES.
>> THE PAPERWORK'S BEEN DONE, AS
OF 1:30 THE PAPERWORK WAS DONE.
THE USUAL DRILL IS THE FUNERAL
HOMES CALL US AND AS SOON AS THE
PAPERWORK'S DONE, WE CALL THEM
BACK.
THAT PROCESS WAS COMPLETED FOR
THE CHILDREN AT 1:30 TODAY.
>> YOU TRANSPORTED THE BODIES
WHERE?
>> TO OUR OFFICE IN FARMINGTON.
>> OKAY.
HOW DID YOU TRANSPORT THEM?
>> WE HAVE TRANSPORT VEHICLES.
>> SO HOW MANY VEHICLES?
>> WE HAVE THREE VEHICLES AND A
LOT OF GUYS THAT DRIVE THEM.
>> VANS OR.
>> ACTUALLY, ONE OF THE
HIGHLIGHTS OF MY ADMINISTRATION
IS THAT WE MAKE THEM AS
NONDESCRIPT AND UN-MARKED AS
POSSIBLE.
>> ONE LAST --
>> JUST TO FOIL YOU GUYS.
NO, THEY STARTED OUT AT 6:00.
>> WHEN YOU REMOVED THE BODIES,
CAN YOU TELL US HOW THE NUMBERS
WERE AND LIST THE VICTIMS IN
BOTH OF THOSE CLASSES?
>> I DON'T HAVE THE DIFFERENTIAL
BETWEEN THE TWO CLASSROOMS.
>> WERE THE MAJORITY OF ADULTS
FOUND IN THE FRONT OFFICE OR IN
THE CLASSROOMS.
>> I'M GOING TO LET THE POLICE
HANDLE THAT BECAUSE THEY'RE THE
SCENE GUYS.
>> YOU SAID YOU'RE GOING TO
EXAMINE THE BODIES OF NANCY
LANZA AND HER SON TOMORROW, IS
THAT CORRECT?
>> YES.
>> WILL YOU BE DOING THAT
PERSONALLY?
>> YEAH, IT JUST SO HAPPENED IT
WAS MY WEEKEND.
>> DOCTOR, YOU SAID YOU CAN'T
CONFIRM THAT THE GUNSHOT WOUNDS
OF THE ASSAIL" ARE
SELF-INFLICTED?
>> I JUST --
>> YOU DON'T KNOW?
>> I CAN'T TECHNICALLY MAKE THAT
DIAGNOSIS UNTIL I EXAMINE HIM,
OKAY?
I DON'T WANT TO BELABOR THE
OBVIOUS.
THAT'S WHAT EVERYBODY BELIEVES
AT THIS POINT BUT IN TERMS OF MY
FISHERY RESPONSIBILITIES, I
HAVEN'T EXECUTED THEM YET.
OKAY?
ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
AS THE DOCTOR STATED, THE TWO
ADDITIONAL POSTMORTEM
EXAMINATIONS WILL BE CONDUCTED
TOMORROW.
WE'LL HAVE ADDITIONAL
INFORMATION RELATIVE TO THE
RESULTS OF THOSE EXAMINATIONS
TOMORROW.
AGAIN, I WOULD IMPLORE YOU AS
HAS BEEN STATED MANY TIMES,
WE'RE ASKING FOR PRIVACY FOR THE
FAMILIES.
AS WE'VE STATED BEFORE, THE
COLONEL HAS IN FACT ASSIGNED A
TROOPER AND OR OFFICERS TO EACH
FAMILY TO PROVIDE AN OPEN LINE
OF COMMUNICATIONING TO THEM FROM
US.
AND THEY WILL BE WITH THE
FAMILIES AS THE ALL TIMES IN AN
EFFORT TO INSTILL THAT PRIVACY.
WE DO HAVE A LIST OF THE
DECEASED.
I'D ASK YOU TO SHARE.
WE'LL PUT IT UP ON OUR WEBSITE
IF YOU DON'T GET ONE.
TROOPER GRANT WILL BE OUT BEHIND
US AND SHE'LL BE HANDING OUT.
PLEASE TAKE ONE PER UNIT, IF YOU
WILL.
AND AGAIN, IF YOU DON'T GET ONE,
IT WILL BE ON THE WEBSITE WITHIN
THE HOUR.
I'M SORRY.
>> WHAT'S THE ADDRESS.
>> ANY SEARCH ENGINE TO CONNECT
TO THE STATE POLICE WEBSITE.
I'LL TAKE ANY BRIEF QUESTIONS.
AGAIN, UNDERSTANDING, PLEASE,
THAT THIS STILL IS AN ACTIVE
CASE.
WE STILL ARE ACTIVELY PURSUING
LEADS AND WE ARE STILL
ANTICIPATE TO DO SO FOR THE NEXT
24 TO 48 HOURS.
SIR?
>> WE DIDN'T DISCUSS THE
LOCATION OF ANY OF THE WEAPONRY
AT ALL.
THERE'S BEEN A LOT OF
SPECULATION OUT THERE RELATIVE
TO THE LOCATION OF THE WEAPONS.
AND WE'D LIKE TO DO THAT WHEN GT
THE CALIBER, ABOUT THE OWNERSHIP
AND ABOUT -- SO I'M GOING TO
HOLD THAT QUESTION UNTIL
PROBABLY TOMORROW MORNING, OKAY?
YES, SIR.
>> TWO QUESTIONS.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL US, WERE ALL
THREE OF THE WEAPONS FIRED, AND
NUMBER TWO, WHAT CAN YOU TELL US
ABOUT A PREVIOUS ALTERCATION
INVOLVING THE GUNMAN AT THE
SCHOOL?
>> OKAY.
FIRST QUESTION I CANNOT ANSWER.
I'LL HAVE TO GET THAT
INFORMATION FOR YOU.
I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S THAT SIMPLE.
THE SECOND QUESTION IS, THERE
HAS BEEN TALK AND SPECULATION
ABOUT THAT.
BUT IN CONVERSATIONS WITH THE
SUPERINTENDENT AND THE
AUTHORITIES HERE IN TOWN, THERE
IS NO INFORMATION ABOUT ANY
CONFRONTATION.
>> LIEUTENANT, WHAT WAS THE
MOTHER DOING WITH THIS SORT OF
WEAPONRY IN HER HOUSE WHEN SHE
HAD A SON THAT HAD SOME MENTAL
ISSUES?
>> THAT'S SOMETHING CERTAINLY WE
NEED TO LOOK AT AND OUR
INVESTIGATORS WILL PEEL BACK THE
ONION AND LOOK AT THE LAYERS IN
THEIR INVESTIGATION.
>> THAT'S PRETTY LARGE FIRE
POWER.
>> AGAIN, WE'LL HAVE TO EXAMINE
THAT SIR.
YES, SIR.
>> DOES THAT MEAN THAT NO
ALTERCATION HAPPENED OR THERE IS
NO INFORMATION?
>> THERE HAVE BEEN NO REPORTS
FILED OF ANY ALTERCATION IN THE
SCHOOL INVOLVING THE INDIVIDUAL.
>> CAN YOU TELL US ANYTHING
ABOUT THIS ASPERINGER'S AND HIS
CONDITION AND STATE?
>> I CAN TELL YOU WE HAVE NOT
OFFICIALLY IDENTIFIED HIM AT
THIS TIME AND IT'S OUR POLICY
UNTIL POSITIVE IDENTIFICATION
AND POSTMORTEM IS COMPLETE, WE
CAN'T DISCUSS THE FACTS AND
CIRCUMSTANCES OF THE DECEASED.
YES, SIR.
>> [ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ].
>> NO, SIR.
SPEAKING WITH THE
SUPERINTENDENT, THERE WAS NO
RELATION AT ALL.
ONE MORE QUESTION.
>> CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT THE
LATINO FAMILIES THAT NEED HELP
WITH COMMUNICATION?
>> WHAT'S VERY IMPORTANT TO NOTE
AND I WOULD BE NEGLECTFUL NOT TO
MENTION THIS.
THE SUPPORT FROM PEOPLE NOT ONLY
IN THE COMMUNITY BUT FIRST OF
ALL ESPECIALLY IN THE COMMUNITY
OF NEWTOWN HAS BEEN OUTSTANDING.
THE SUPPORT OUTSIDE OF THE
COMMUNITY HAS BEEN MORE THAN
OUTSTANDING.
THE OUTPOURING OF ASSISTANCE,
THE OFFER OF HELP, AS HAS BEEN
REPORTED, NOT ONLY AS NEWTOWN
POLICE ARE INVOLVED, STATE
POLICE ARE INVOLVED, FEDERAL
AUTHORITIES, OTHER STATE
AGENCIES, OTHER LOCAL POLICE
DEPARTMENTS, OTHER
PARAPROFESSIONALS,
PROFESSIONALS, THEY'RE ALL HERE
AND SUPPORT THE FAMILY.
WE'RE CERTAINLY ATTEMPTING AND
WE WILL AND WE HAD PROVIDED
SUPPORT FOR THE FIRST
RESPONDERS.
THE FIRE, POLICE, EMS AND WE'RE
GOING TO CONTINUE TO DO THAT AND
WE'LL DO THAT AS LONG AS
NECESSARY.
I'M GOING TO THANK YOU FOR THIS.
I'M GOING TO SIMPLY SAY TO YOU,
THIS IS THE LAST BRIEFING FOR
TODAY.
WE WILL BE HERE TOMORROW
MORNING.
I'LL GIVE YOU ANY UPDATES
TOMORROW MORNING.
BUT THERE WILL BE NO MORE
BRIEFINGS OR INTERVIEW.
IF ANYTHING WERE TO BREAK,
BREAKING NEWS, I WOULD DIRECT
YOU TO OUR WEBSITE.
WE WILL POST IT ON OUR WEBSITE.
AGAIN, WE DON'T ANTICIPATE
ANYTHING AS OUR INVESTIGATORS
CONTINUE THEIR WORK.
>> ANYTHING MORE ON A MOTIVE?
>> NO, THERE IS NOTHING MORE
TODAY.
NOTHING MORE AT ALL.
>> CAN YOU TELL US THE TIME THE
FEMALE WAS SHOT?
>> I DON'T KNOW, SIR.
I'M NOT GOING TO READ THE NAMES.
I'LL PROVIDE COPIES.
I HAVE SOME.
KELLY GRANT -- TROOPER GRANT IS
BACK THERE WITH OTHER COPIES.
>> THAT WILL BE LIEUTENANT VANCE
FROM THE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE, HOLDING THESE PRESS
CONFERENCES OVER THE LAST 24
HOURS-PLUS.
HE SAID A COUPLE THINGS ABOUT
THE CASE BEFORE HE BEGAN.
HE REALLY MENTIONED THAT HE WAS
ONCE AGAIN GOING TO PLAY FOR THE
FAMILIES OF THESE CHILDREN WHO
ARE -- HAVE BEEN KILLED IN THIS
TERRIBLE TRAGEDY THEY WOULD BE
LEFT ALONE IN SOLITUDE.
HE'S ASSIGNED EACH FAMILY, HE
REMINDED US, A TROOPER, TO MAKE
SURE THAT HAPPENS.
HE SAID A COUPLE THINGS ABOUT
THE CASE STILL BEING ACTIVE.
AND HE SAID THERE'S STILL
INFORMATION THAT THEY'RE STILL
TRYING TO GET ABOUT THE CALIBER
OF THE WEAPONRY, THE OWNERSHIP
OF THE GUNS.
AND SO THEY HAVE NO INFORMATION
AT THIS POINT THEY ARE RELEASING
OFFICIALLY, AT LEAST IN THIS
KIND OF PRESS CONFERENCE FORMAT.
HE SAID THEY HAVEN'T EVEN
OFFICIALLY IDENTIFIED THE
ALLEGED SHOOTER.
AND THEY'RE WAITING FOR THE
POSTMORTEM THAT WE KNOW WILL
TAKE PLACE TOMORROW.
BUT HE ALSO POINTED OUT -- WORD
OF THE COMMUNITY HAS BEEN
OUTSTANDING AND THE SUPPORT OF
THE FOLKS OUTSIDE OF THE
COMMUNITY, HE SAYS, HAS BEEN
EVEN MORE THAN OUTSTANDING.
BEFORE WE HEARD FROM LIEUTENANT
VANCE, WE HEARD FROM THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER OF THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT, WAYNE CARVER II,
AND HE STARTED OFF BY SAYING HIS
PRAYERS AND THOUGHTS WERE WITH
THE ENTIRE COMMUNITY.
HAD SOME INFORMATION THAT HE
WANTED TO TALK ABOUT.
NUMBER ONE, ALL THE FOLKS WERE
KILLED BY GUNSHOTS, ALL RULED A
HOMICIDE.
HE BELIEVES THAT THE CHILDREN
ALL WERE FIRST GRADERS WHO WERE
KILLED BY THE GUNMAN.
HE SAID THEY ARE WORKING AT THIS
POINT FROM A TEMPORARY FACILITY,
TAKING PHOTOS AND THAT, IN FACT,
BY 1:30 THIS AFTERNOON, ALL OF
THE AUTOPSIES HAD BEEN
COMPLETED, AND THE EXAMINATIONS
HAD BEEN COMPLETED ON THE
CHILDREN.
AND THAT THE MORTUARIES HAD HAD
ALL BEEN CALLED, MEANING AT THAT
POINT THEY WOULD BE READY TO
DELIVER THE BODIES BACK TO THE
FAMILIES OF THE CHILDREN SO FAR.
HE SAID THAT THERE WERE
EXAMINATIONS STILL TO BE DONE.
THE SHOOTER AND HIS MOTHER, THE
ALLEGED SHOOTER AND HIS MOTHER.
THOSE EXAMINATIONS, THOSE
POSTMORTEMS WILL BE DONE
TOMORROW.
THEY WILL -- HE TALKED ABOUT THE
WOUNDS.
HE SAID THAT THE WOUNDS WERE
CAUSED BY ONE WEAPON.
AT LEAST THOSE THEY'VE LOOKED AT
SO FAR AND THAT WAS THE
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE.
HE SAID HE HIMSELF DID SEVEN
AUTOPSIES AND TWO OF THEM WERE
CLOSE-RANGE SHOOTINGS AND HE
SAID HE USED PICTURES FROM THE
FAMILY MEMBERS TO I.D. THOSE
BODIES.
HE SAID THAT AS LONG AS HE HAS
BEEN DOING THIS, IT WAS A VERY
TOUGH THING THAT WHILE HE WAS
HOLDING UP WELL, HE HAS A LOT OF
EXPERIENCE, HE SAID HE HAS NOT
COLLAPSED EMOTIONALLY YET,
ECHLZING THE WORD YET, BECAUSE
HE SAID THIS IS ONE OF THE
TOUGHEST THINGS HE HAS SEEN IN
HIS CAREER.
HE BELIEVES THAT EVERYBODY OF
THE 26 KILLED, AND THEN THE TWO
OTHERS, INCLUDING THE SHOOTER
AND HIS MOTHER, OF THOSE 26, HE
SAYS HE BELIEVES THAT EACH ONE
WAS HIT BY MORE THAN ONE BULLET.
WOUNDS DESCRIBED WHEN HE WAS
ASKED BY REPORTERS, HE SAID ALL
OVER.
AND GAVE SOME DETAILS.
BUT NOT VERY MANY ABOUT THE
SCENE INSIDE OF THAT SHOOTING.
SO WE'RE GETTING A FEW MORE
DETAILS FROM THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER WHO WE HAVE BEEN
WAITING TO HEAR FROM.
AND ALSO FROM THE LIEUTENANT
VANCE FROM THE STATE POLICE WHO
SAID THIS WOULD BE IT IN TERMS
OF UPDATES FOR THE REST OF THE
DAY.
THEY HAVE BEEN VERY GOOD AT
UPDATING REPORTERS DURING THE
DAY.
BUT ALSO REMINDING THEM THEY
WANT THE FAMILY MEMBERS WHOSE
CHILDREN ARE DECEASED TO BE LEFT
ALONE, LEFT IN SOLITUDE AS THEY
ARE GRAPPLING WITH THIS
TERRIBLE, TERRIBLE CIRCUMSTANCE.
SO THAT IS THEIR UPDATE FROM
THIS EVENING PRESS CONFERENCE,
THE LAST ONE OF THE DAY.
AND, OF COURSE, THEY WERE THEN
ABLE TO RELEASE THE NAMES OF
THOSE WHO HAVE BEEN KILLED WHO
THEY HAVE ALREADY DONE THE
POSTMORTEMS ON.
SO THAT IS WHERE IT STANDS RIGHT
NOW.
DEB FEYERICK IS UPDATING FOR US
OTHER INFORMATION, AS WELL.
AND I WANT TO THROW IT RIGHT
BACK TO DEB.
>> SOLE DAD, WHAT WE'RE
LEARNING, A LAW ENFORCEMENT
SOURCE WITH KNOWLEDGE OF THIS
INVESTIGATION HAS SAID THAT NO
SUICIDE NOTE HAS YET BEEN
DISCOVERED ON OR NEAR THE
ALLEGED SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA.
APPARENTLY HE DID LIVE ALONE
WITH HIS MOTHER.
THAT IS CONSISTENT WITH EARLIER
REPORTS THAT AFTER A SEPARATION
FOLLOWED BY A DIVORCE THAT HE
WAS WITH HIS MOTHER, LIVING IN
THAT HOME.
THE MOTHER -- THERE'S A BIG
QUESTION AS TO WHY THIS SCHOOL.
WHY THIS PARTICULAR SCHOOL.
WELL, IT APPEARS THE MOTHER,
ACCORDING TO THIS SOURCE, WAS
NOT A TEACHER AT THE SCHOOL.
SHE MAY HAVE HAD A MINOR ROLE, A
SUBSTITUTE OR AN AIDE.
THEY'RE STILL LOOKING INTO WHAT
SHE DID THERE.
BUT SHE WAS DEFINITELY NOT AN
ON-STAFF TEACHER, ACCORDING TO
THIS SOURCE.
FROM EVERYTHING LAW ENFORCEMENT
HAS SEEN SO FAR, THE ALLEGED
SHOOTER ACTED ALONE.
AUTHORITIES ARE FURTHER LOOKING
INTO WHAT HE MAY HAVE SUFFERED
FROM.
WHAT HIS MENTAL ISSUES WERE OR
HIS MENTAL STATE, HIS MENTAL
CONDITION.
THE SOURCE WOULD NOT PROVIDE ANY
DETAILS, NOR WOULD POLICE, AS A
MATTER OF FACT.
THEY ARE REFUSING TO SPECULATE
ON ANY POSSIBLE MENTAL
CONDITIONS THAT HE MAY OR MAY
NOT HAVE HAD.
THEY ARE CHECKING.
INVESTIGATORS ARE CHECKING TO
SEE WHO THE SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA,
THE ALLEGED SHOOTER KNEW, EITHER
SOCIALLY, PROFESSIONALLY, WHO
HIS TEACHERS WERE, WHAT DOCTORS
HE MAY HAVE BEEN SEEING.
THERE'S STILL A FATHER IN THIS
PICTURE, WHO LIVES IN ANOTHER
TOWN, A COUPLE MILES AWAY.
THEY'RE TRYING TO LEARN AS MUCH
AS THEY CAN ABOUT THIS YOUNG MAN
AND WHY HE DID WHAT HE DID.
ALSO, WE'RE BEING TOLD BY AN
INVESTIGATOR THAT THE MOM --
AGAIN, NOT CLEAR WHETHER SHE WAS
A SUBSTITUTE OR MAY HAVE BEEN
UNEMPLOYED.
BUT IT DOESN'T SEEM, AT LEAST
NOT RIGHT NOW, THAT FINANCIAL
ISSUES PLAYED ANY SORT OF A ROLE
IN WHAT HAPPENED OR WHY IT
HAPPENED.
THE SOURCE ALSO SAID THERE IS A
QUESTION OF IDENTIFICATION
INITIALLY.
THE BROTHER, RYAN LANZA, HAD
BEEN IDENTIFIED AS THE POTENTIAL
SHOOTER.
BUT APPARENTLY WE ARE TOLD BY
AUTHORITIES THAT THE ALLEGED
SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA, DID NOT
HAVE ANY IDENTIFICATION ON HIM
BELONGING TO HIS BROTHER WHEN HE
WAS FOUND.
AND YOU COMMENTED ON IT, AND THE
PARENTS WERE NOT ABLE TO
IDENTIFY THEIR CHILDREN BY GOING
TO SEE THEIR CHILDREN.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINERS ACTUALLY
TOOL PHOTOS SO THE PARENTS COULD
IDENTIFY THEIR CHILDREN THAT
WAY.
AND THAT JUST HAS TO BE SO
PAINFUL.
SO OVERWHELMING.
AND RIGHT NOW, SO MANY PEOPLE
ARE OVERWHELMED WITH GRIEF AND
SADNESS AND PAIN, MISSING THEIR
LOVED ONES, TRYING TO UNDERSTAND
WHAT HAPPENED.
TRYING TO UNDERSTAND WHAT CANNOT
BE UNDERSTOOD.
>>> WELCOME, EVERYBODY.
WE'RE COMING TO YOU LIVE THIS
AFTERNOON AS WE CONTINUE TO
COVER AN ABSOLUTE TRAGEDY HERE
AT CONNECTICUT, THE CONNECTICUT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SHOOTING.
LOTS TO UPDATE YOU ON AS IN THE
LAST FEW MINUTES WE HAVE HAD AN
UPDATE FROM THE CONNECTICUT
STATE MEDICAL EXAMINER, AND ALSO
THE STATE POLICE HERE GIVING US
SOME OF THE LATEST DETAILS ABOUT
THIS CASE.
YOU JUST HEARD A MOMENT AGO DEB
FEYERICK GIVING US THE VERY
LATEST INFORMATION COMING TO US
FROM -- DETAILS ABOUT THE
SHOOTER.
AND, OF COURSE, AT THIS POINT
THERE ARE REALLY NO MORE WORDS,
ONLY HOPE, I GUESS, IN SOME WAYS
THAT THE FAMILIES OF THOSE WHO
HAVE LOST EVERYTHING, THEIR
PRIZE POSSESSION, THEIR
CHILDREN.
FAMILIES HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT WILL SOME DAY BE
ABLE TO FIND THEIR WAY THROUGH
THIS TERRIBLE GRIEF AND THEN THE
NATION WILL COME TO GRIPS WITH
YET ANOTHER TERRIBLE TRAGEDY.
SO WE BEGIN TODAY WITH WHAT WE
KNOW SO FAR ABOUT THIS SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
ALL THE VICTIMS HAVE NOW BEEN
REMOVED FROM THE SCHOOL.
THEY HAVE BEEN IDENTIFIED,
POSTMORTEMS HAVE BEEN DONE.
SOURCES TOLD INVESTIGATORS THAT
THE ALLEGED SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA,
WAS INVOLVED IN AN ALTERCATION
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
WITH FOUR ADULTS THURSDAY AND
THREE OF THOSE ADULTS WERE
KILLED ON FRIDAY.
BUT WE JUST HEARD AN UPDATE A
MOMENT AGO COMING TO US FROM THE
LAW ENFORCEMENT THE SOURCE WHERE
HE SAID THAT THEY HAD NO
INFORMATION, IN FACT, ABOUT A
CONFRONTATION.
SO THAT IS SOME CONTRADICTORY
INFORMATION ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
THERE.
WE ALSO KNOW THAT LANZA
SUPPOSEDLY TRIED TO BUY A GUN AT
A SPORTING GOODS STORE NEAR
NEWTOWN ON TUESDAY.
HE WAS UNSUCCESSFUL.
NO DETAILS AT THIS POINT,
THOUGH, ON WHY EXACTLY HE WAS
UNSUCCESSFUL.
HE LIVED ALONE WITH HIS MOTHER,
NANCY, WHO HE KILLED BEFORE HE
WENT ON THAT RAMPAGE AT THE
SCHOOL.
HIS MOTHER WAS NOT A TEACHER, WE
NOW KNOW, AT THE SCHOOL.
BUT SHE MAY HAVE HAD SOME KIND
OF A ROLE AT THE SCHOOL AS A
SUBSTITUTE TEACHER OR POSSIBLY
AN AIDE.
LANZA DID NOT HAVE HIS BROTHER
RYAN'S IDENTIFICATION ON HIM
WHEN, IN FACT, HIS BODY WAS
FOUND.
THAT WAS OTHER CONTRADICTORY
INFORMATION THAT WE WERE HEARING
YESTERDAY.
SO ALL OF THIS AT THIS POINT
LEAVES US WITH MANY MORE
QUESTIONS AND ANSWERS ABOUT A
POSSIBLE MOTIVE OF THE SUSPECTED
SHOOTER.
MARY SNOW HAS A CLOSER LOOK AT
THAT FOR US.
>> SHORTLY AFTER FRIDAY'S
HORRIFIC SHOOTINGS, POLICE AND
S.W.A.T. TEAMS DESCENDED UPON
THE LANZA HOME.
YOU CAN'T SEE IT.
IT'S BIND ME.
AND IT'S CLOSED OFF BY POLICE.
AND INVESTIGATORS ARE NOW
SUGGESTING THAT THEY ARE PIECING
TOGETHER INFORMATION LEADING TO
POSSIBLE ANSWERS ABOUT HOW AND
WHY THIS HAPPENED.
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE OF THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE SAYING
THAT IN HIS WORDS, GOOD EVIDENCE
IS BEING RECOVERED BUT HE DID
NOT GO INTO DETAIL.
IN TERMS OF THE WEAPONS USED, WE
DO KNOW THAT THREE WEAPONS WERE
RECOVERED AT THE SCENE OF THE
SHOOTING NEAR THE SUSPECT'S
BODY.
THERE WERE TWO HANDGUNS AND A
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE.
CNN HAS BEEN REPORTING THAT
THOSE GUNS WERE PURCHASED BY HIS
MOTHER, NANCY LANZA.
AND THERE'S NOT MUCH WE DO KNOW
ABOUT NANCY LANZA.
WE SPOKE TO A NEIGHBOR EARLIER
IN THE DAY, AND SHE SAID SHE
KNEW HER, BUT THERE WAS NOTHING
OUT OF THE ORDINARY THAT SHE
COULD SEE.
>> SHE WAS LIKE A NORMAL --
ANYBODY ELSE IN THIS
NEIGHBORHOOD.
YOU KNOW, DECORATE THE HOUSE,
AND THE HOUSE WAS ALWAYS, YOU
KNOW, PRISTINE.
SHE WAS JUST LIKE ANY OTHER
HOUSEWIFE.
>> Reporter: AS FOR ADAM LANZA,
FORMER CLASSMATES DESCRIBE HIM
AS BEING A SMART STUDENT,
SOMEONE WHO WAS QUIET, KEPT TO
HIMSELF, A NEIGHBOR WHO KNEW HIM
IN RECENT YEARS DESCRIBED HIM AS
TROUBLED.
MARY SNOW, CNN, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> WE WANT TO BRING IN CHIEF
MEDICAL CORRESPONDENT DR. SANJAY
GUPTA.
LET'S FIRST TALK ABOUT THE
CHILDREN.
POST TRAUMATIC STRESS.
AS THE DAY GOES ON, YOU SEE SOME
OF THE PARENTS WALKING AROUND
WITH THEIR -- THEIR CHILDREN,
COMING TO SOME OF THESE
MEMORIALS THAT HAVE BEEN SET UP.
IS THAT A GOOD THING OR BETTER
THING TO NOT BRING THE CHILDREN
AROUND?
>> EVERYONE WE'VE BEEN TALKING
TO -- WE WENT TO THE CRISIS
CENTER, WHICH HAS BEEN SET UP
HERE AT ANOTHER ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, REED ELEMENTARY.
AND THE PEOPLE THAT YOU TALK TO
OVER THERE SAY IT IS A GOOD
THING.
AND, IN FACT, IF YOU GO TO THAT
PARKING LOT -- I DIDN'T KNOW
WHAT TO EXPECT THERE.
OBVIOUSLY, IT'S SET UP AT A
DIFFERENT SCHOOL.
BUT IT WAS FULL.
AND WHAT I ALSO NOTICED, PEOPLE
WERE GOING IN, FAMILIES, SMALL
CHILDREN, AND THEY WERE STAYING
FOR A LONG TIME.
SO THIS WASN'T A SORT OF QUICK
IN AND OUT SORT OF THING.
THE WHOLE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SET
UP AS A COUNSELING CENTER.
SO PSYCHIATRISTS, PSYCHOLOGISTS,
CHILDREN'S COUNSELORS
SPECIFICALLY IN THERE.
SO THEY'RE ENCOURAGING THIS.
AND THE WAY THEY SORT OF PUT IT
TO ME, YOU THINK ABOUT THE
COMMUNITY SORT OF AS AN
INDIVIDUAL ITSELF.
MEANING THAT THE IDEA THAT
PEOPLE ALL SORT OF REALIZE
THEY'RE IN IT TOGETHER, AT LEAST
DOES SOMETHING TO MITIGATE THOSE
FEELINGS OF ISOLATION WHICH CAN
BE SO PROBLEMATIC.
SO GOOD THING, IS WHAT I'M
HEARING.
EVERYTHING YOU'RE SEEING AROUND
YOU RIGHT NOW, THIS IS -- I
THINK WHAT THEY WANT.
>> WHAT WILL THEY DO FOR THE
CHILDREN?
KATE BOLDUAN HAD A REMARKABLE
STORY OF A LITTLE BOY SHE.
SHE TALKED TO HIS PARENTS WHO
RAN PAST THE SHOOTER, KILLING
HIS TEACHER AND KILLING SOME OF
HIS CLASSMATES.
HOW DOES A CHILD LIKE THAT WHO
AT THIS MOMENT SHE DESCRIBED AS
CALM AND MATTER OF FACT AND
HELPFUL TO DETECTIVES.
BUT ONE HAS TO IMAGINE DOWN THE
ROAD, HE'S GOING TO BE
COMPLETELY TRAUMATIZED.
>> YES.
AND PTSD IS SOMETHING WE'RE USED
TO TALKING ABOUT WITH ADULTS.
BUT YOU KNOW, I DID A LITTLE BIT
OF RESEARCH, BECAUSE THERE ARE
SOME STUDIES ON LOOKING AT KIDS
SPECIFICALLY.
AND WHAT YOU FIND IS AFTER THIS
SORT OF THING, ESPECIALLY IF
SOMEONE HAS SEEN THE VIOLENCE,
THIS IS A BIG SORT OF PIVOT
POINT.
BEING IN THE SCHOOL, OBVIOUSLY,
PROBLEMATIC.
BEING IN THE COMMUNITY,
OBVIOUSLY OF CONCERN.
EVEN IN THIS COUNTRY.
BUT IF YOU SEE SOMETHING, THE
RATES ARE MUCH HIGHER, AS YOU
MIGHT GUESS.
77% OF PEOPLE, EVEN 3 TO 4
MONTHS OUT, HAD EVIDENCE OF
PTSD.
NOW, CHILDREN TEND TO BE MORE
RESILIENT, AND BY THAT, YOU
KNOW, GETTING BACK INTO SOME
SORT OF NORMAL PATTERN OF
BEHAVIOR SEEMS TO MAKE A BIG
DIFFERENCE.
BUT YOU KNOW, WE TALK ABOUT THIS
STUFF ALL THE TIME.
THERE ISN'T A LOT OF PRECEDENT.
WE WOULD LIKE TO SAY WE HAVE
TONS OF STUDIES TO BASE THIS ON.
WHAT WE'RE REPORTING ON IS A
FAIRLY UNPRECEDENTED SITUATION
IN TERMS OF ITS SCOPE WITH THIS
AGE CHILDREN.
>> THERE WAS A QUESTION THROWN
TO LIEUTENANT VANCE, THE GUY
HOLDING ALL THESE PRESS
CONFERENCES, AND THEY WERE
ASKING ABOUT THE MENTAL STATE OF
THE ALLEGED SHOOTER, WHO IS --
THEY STILL HAVE NOT DONE A
POSTMORTEM ON HIM, AND THEY'RE
RELEASING VERY LITTLE
INFORMATION.
IS THERE A CONNECTION BETWEEN
THESE MOOSE KILLINGS AND PEOPLE
WHO ARE MENTALLY ILL?
IS IT -- OTHER PEOPLE HAVE SAID,
I KNOW HIS BROTHER SAID THAT HE
HAD A KIND OF AUTISM.
HE TOLD AUTHORITIES APPARENTLY
THAT.
IS THERE ANY CORRELATION BETWEEN
AUTISM AND ANY KIND OF VIOLENCE?
MY NEPHEW IS AUTISTIC AND I
DON'T KNOW OF ANY STUDIES THAT
LINK THAT.
>> I THINK THERE AREN'T ANY
STUDIES.
AND TWO POINTS HERE.
FIRST OF ALL, I WOULDN'T THINK
OF AUTISM AS A MENTAL ILLNESS.
IT IS A NEURAL DEVELOPMENTAL
DISORDER.
AND IF YOU LOOK AT THE STUDIES,
WHATOU FIND IS WHILE THERE IS
A POSSIBILITY OF MORE OUTBURSTS,
SORT OF REACTIVE VIOLENCE, THE
IDEA OF PLANNED VIOLENCE WHERE
SOMEONE ACTUALLY PLANS OUT
SOMETHING METHODICALLY, THAT
DOESN'T CORRELATE.
THE BEST STUDY, ONE EVERYONE
QUOTES, A STUDY OF 132 PATIENTS,
NOT THAT BIG A STUDY, BUT ONE OF
THE BEST ONES OUT THERE, ONLY 3
PEOPLE IN THAT 132-PEOPLE STUDY
HAD ANY EVIDENCE OF SPECIFIC
VIOLENCE.
AND EVEN THAT AGAIN WAS MAINLY
REACTIVE.
NOT THIS SORT OF PLANNED
VIOLENCE.
I DON'T THINK THERE IS A LINK.
>> AS YOU KNOW, IF YOU GO
ONLINE, THE DISCUSSION AND
DEBATE AROUND THIS TERRIBLE
TRAGEDY IS CATEGORIZED INTO A
GUN DEBATE.
INTO A DEBATE ABOUT BRINGING
AWARENESS TO MENTAL HEALTH AND A
LACK OF HELP FOR MANY PEOPLE AND
MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES.
LOTS OF CUTS THERE.
AND WHERE THE TWO OF THOSE
THINGS INTERSECT.
AND, AGAIN, NOT A LOT IS KNOWN
ABOUT THE SHOOTER SO IT'S HARD
TO SAY.
TALK ABOUT THE MENTAL HEALTH
ASPECT.
WE HAVE DONE A LOT OF
CONVERSATIONS ABOUT GUNS AND GUN
CONTROL.
MANY CUTS WE HAVE SEEN IN THIS
COUNTRY ON MENTAL HEALTH.
AND IT'S HARD FOR PEOPLE WHO ARE
MENTALLY ILL SOMETIMES TO GET
HELP.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
AND I'M GLAD YOU BRING IT UP.
I'VE REPORTED ON THIS QUITE A
BIT, AND I KNOW YOU HAVE, AS
WELL.
BUT THERE IS THIS WHOLE NOTION
OF SOMETHING THEY CALL PARITY.
AND WHAT THAT MEANS, DO YOU
TREAT MENTAL ILLNESS THE SAME AS
PHYSICAL ILLNESS, DIABETES OR
HEART DISEASE, THEY GO TO THE
DOCTOR.
WITH MENTAL ILLNESS, OFTENTIMES
IT'S VERY HARD TO EVEN GET THE
DIAGNOSIS BECAUSE OF LACK OF
RESOURCES.
AND EVEN HARDER TO GET
TREATMENT, BECAUSE OF LACK OF
RESOURCES.
SO YOU KNOW, IT ISN'T ALWAYS
JUST MISSING THE WARNING SIGNS.
FAMILIES MAY SEE THE WARNING
SIGNS.
COMMUNITY MEMBERS MAY SEE
WARNING SIGNS.
BUT THE QUESTION IS WHAT DO YOU
DO AFTER THAT?
ARE THERE RESOURCES IN PLACE?
AND I THINK THESE CUTS THAT YOU
TALK ABOUT -- AGAIN, WE DON'T
KNOW WHAT HAPPENED HERE
SPECIFICALLY.
BUT WITH REGARD TO --
>> OR THAT MENTAL ILLNESS IS
INVOLVED IN ANY WAY.
>> RIGHT.
>> OR EVEN THAT AUTISM IS
INVOLVED IN ANY WAY, BECAUSE WE
HAVE NOT THAT MUCH INFORMATION
ABOUT THE SHOOTER ARE.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
WE DON'T KNOW.
BUT WITH REGARD TO MENTAL
ILLNESS, MORE SORT OF GLOBALLY,
YEAH, IT'S INCREDIBLY
CHALLENGING TO GET THAT.
AND THAT PARITY ISSUE IS
SOMETHING THAT'S COME UP WITH
REGARD TO THE AFFORDABLE CARE
ACT, WITH REGARD TO HOW WE SPEND
RESOURCES GOING FORWARD.
BECAUSE IT JUST -- IT ISN'T ON
PAR WITH PHYSICAL DISEASE.
A LOT OF TIMES WE CAN GET THESE
PATIENTS CARED FOR QUICKLY FOR
THINGS THAT YOU AND I CAN
QUANTIFY, HEART DISEASE,
DIABETES.
IF YOU THINK MENTAL ILLNESS IS
ON THE SAME LEVEL, IT ISN'T IN
THIS COUNTRY.
>> I GUESS IT'S THE
INTERSECTION, AT LEAST FOR ME,
BETWEEN MENTAL ILLNESS AND
ACCESS TO WEAPONS IS REALLY WHAT
ENDS UP BECOMING THE TERRIFYING
COMBINATION IN A LOT OF THESE
CASES.
WE'VE COVERED COLUMBINE.
WE'VE COVERED VIRGINIA TECH.
WE'VE COVERED A NUMBER OF THESE
HORRIFIC SHOOTINGS.
AND THERE NEVER SEEMS TO BE --
PEOPLE ALWAYS SAY TODAY IS NOT
THE DAY TO DISCUSS IT.
AND I'M GOING TO DISAGREE.
I THINK THAT WE HAVE TO DISCUSS
IT.
BOTH MENTAL ILLNESS AND WEAPONS
THAT ARE AVAILABLE SO READILY IN
THIS COUNTRY.
>> YEAH.
YOU KNOW, I THINK CERTAINLY AS A
DOCTOR, I THINK YOU DO SEIZE THE
OPPORTUNITY TO TALK ABOUT THESE
THINGS.
AND WITH REGARD TO MENTAL
ILLNESS, I THINK IT JUST GETS
SHORT SHRIFT EVERY SINGLE TIME.
SO THE FACT THAT PEOPLE ARE
PAYING MORE ATTENTION TO THIS
ISSUE RIGHT NOW, IT MAY LIGHT A
LITTLE BIT OF A TORCH.
AND I THINK YOU'RE RIGHT.
IT IS THAT INTERSECTION.
I DON'T KNOW EXACTLY WHERE THAT
INTERSECTION IS GOING TO LIE,
EXACTLY HOW MUCH WE'RE GOING TO
FOCUS ON MENTAL ILLNESS VERSUS
GUNS OR VICE VERSA, BUT I THINK
YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
>> YOU HAVE THREE DAUGHTERS.
THEY'RE SORT OF IN THE SAME AGE
RANGE.
WHAT DO YOU TELL THEM?
DO YOU LET THEM WATCH TV?
DO YOU TELL THEM NOT TO WATCH
TV?
DO YOU EXPLAIN WHY YOU'RE HERE
REPORTING OR DO YOU NOT TELL
THEM THINGS?
>> I HAVEN'T -- THEY HAVEN'T
BEEN WATCHING TELEVISION.
BUT THEY STILL KNOW.
AND I THINK THAT'S ONE THING
THAT'S PROBABLY CHANGED SINCE
OUR KIDS WERE BORN.
WE THINK BY TURNING OFF THE
TELEVISION THAT COULD INSULATE,
AND IT DOESN'T.
MY 7-YEAR-OLD STILL KNEW BECAUSE
SOCIAL MEDIA AND HER FRIENDS IN
SCHOOL ARE TALKING ABOUT IT.
SHE CALLED ME.
I WAS ACTUALLY IN LOS ANGELES.
SHE CALLED ME ON THE PHONE AND
WE TALKED.
AND I SAID TO HER, YOU KNOW -- I
WAS VERY TRANSPARENT.
I MEAN, I DIDN'T EXPOSE GRAPHIC
DETAILS AND THINGS LIKE THAT.
BUT I THINK I WAS JUST VERY
HONEST.
IT WAS PROBABLY ONE OF THE MOST
HONEST CONVERSATIONS I HAD WITH
MY 7-YEAR-OLD.
>> WHAT DID SHE WANT TO KNOW?
>> SHE WANTED TO KNOW IF THIS
COULD HAPPEN IN HER SCHOOL, WAS
I THINK HER PRIMARY THING.
AND SHE SAID SCHOOLS WERE
SUPPOSED TO BE SAFE.
THAT'S WHAT SHE ASKED ME.
>> HOW DO YOU ANSWER THAT?
BECAUSE SCHOOLS AREN'T SAFE.
EXHIBIT A IS THIS SCHOOL IS NOT
SAFE.
>> I SAID FOR THE MOST PART THEY
ARE SAFE.
BUT OBVIOUSLY THIS HAPPENED.
I SAID THIS NEVER HAPPENED TO ME
WHEN I WENT TO SCHOOL.
IT NEVER HAPPENED TO YOUR MOMMY
WHEN SHE WENT TO SCHOOL.
BUT IT OBVIOUSLY HAPPENED HERE.
AND WE'RE GOING TO DO OUR BEST
TO TRY AND KEEP YOU SAFE.
BUT, YEAH.
I WAS JUST VERY HONEST I THINK
WITH HER.
I THINK NOT BEING HONEST
PROBABLY IS THE WRONG ANSWER.
AS MUCH AS IT'S MAYBE YOUR
TENDENCY TO TRY AND PROTECT AS A
PARENT.
BUT IT JUST DOESN'T SEEM TO BE
THE RIGHT WAY TO DEAL WITH IT.
>> MY KIDS ALWAYS WANT TO KNOW
IF SOMEONE DIED.
DID ANYBODY DIE.
THAT'S ALWAYS THEIR QUESTION.
>> AND I TOLD HER -- YEAH, SHE
KNEW THAT.
AND I CONFIRMED THAT FOR HER.
>> SUCH A TERRIBLE STORY.
SANJAY, THANK YOU.
WE APPRECIATE YOUR INSIGHT ON
THIS.
>>> A COUPLE THINGS WE NOW KNOW
ABOUT THIS CASE.
POLICE ARE TELLING US THE GUNMAN
FORCED HIS WAY INTO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
NO ONE LET HIM IN VOLUNTARILY.
THE SCHOOL INSTALLED A NEW
SECURITY SYSTEM.
THE PRINCIPAL WHO CAME TO THE
SCHOOL IN 2010 CREATED THE NEW
SECURITY SYSTEM SO DOORS WOULD
LOCK AT 9:30 A.M.
VISITORS WERE SUPPOSED TO RING A
BELL AND THEN THEY WOULD HAVE TO
GET CLEARANCE FROM THE FRONT
OFFICE TO WALK THROUGH THOSE
LOCKED DOORS.
THEY WOULD HAVE TO BE LET IN.
WE DON'T KNOW WHETHER THE
SHOOTER BURST INTO THE SCHOOL
AND STARTED SHOOTING BEFORE OR
AFTER 9:30 A.M.
WE WANT TO GET TO LUKE A RETIRED
POLICE OFFICER IN NEW YORK, NOW
RUNS A RETIRED SECURITY AGENCY.
WE KEEP HAVING THESE
DISCUSSIONS.
HOW DO YOU PREVENT THIS TRAGEDY?
AND SOME PEOPLE WILL SAY IT'S
ABOUT GUNS AND OTHER PEOPLE, AS
SANJAY AND I WERE TALKING ABOUT,
WILL SAY IT'S ABOUT MENTAL
HEALTH.
AND OTHERS WILL SAY EXAMINE THE
SCHOOL OR PUT A GUARD OR POLICE
OFFICER AT THE SCHOOL.
WHAT DO YOU THINK THE ANSWER IS?
>> WELL, I SAID IN EARLIER
DISCUSSION, I DON'T BELIEVE IN A
SINGLE CAUSALITY.
I THINK THERE ARE A NUMBER OF
ISSUES THAT HAVE TO BE
ADDRESSED.
CLEARLY, WE HAVE TO ADDRESS THE
GUN ISSUE IN OUR COUNTRY.
I AM A SUPPORTER OF THE SECOND
AMENDMENT.
BUT I'M NOT A FOOL.
WE HAVE A PROBLEM.
WE HAVE A PROBLEM WITH MENTAL
HEALTH.
IF WE'RE REALLY GOING TO REVERT
TO PUTTING ARMED SECURITY AT
EVERY SCHOOL IN OUR COUNTRY, I
THINK WE HAVE A RATHER HUGE
UNDERTAKING.
AND I'M NOT CONVINCED THAT'S THE
METHOD.
I DO THINK THAT FOR SCHOOLS,
THOUGH, THEY SHOULD HAVE A TYPE
OF SAFE ROOM WHICH COULD BE USED
AS A CLASSROOM.
IN OTHER WORDS, YOU CHANGE OR
UPGRADE THE QUALITY OF THE DOOR,
AND THE LOCKS.
THEREFORE, IT MAKES IT VERY
DIFFICULT TO PENETRATE THEM OR
BREACH THEM.
AND AS FAR AS THE ENTRY INTO THE
SCHOOL, YOU KNOW, THE SCHOOLS
ARE ON THE RIGHT TRACK.
THEY WANT TO BUZZ YOU IN.
THE PROBLEM, AGAIN, AND AS WE
SAW IN THIS INSTANCE, THIS
INDIVIDUAL WAS DETERMINED TO
ENTER THE SCHOOL.
HE GOT IN.
I DON'T THINK THAT WE'RE GOING
TO COME TO ANY TYPE OF OVERNIGHT
SOLUTION TO WHAT TRANSPIRED HERE
TODAY.
I THINK WE HAVE TO REALLY JUST
WRAP OUR ARMS AROUND THE GRAVITY
OF IT.
AND IN OUR HEARTS KNOW THAT WE
WANT TO PREVENT IT.
AND COME TO A COMMON GROUND
INSTEAD OF MAKING THIS A
POLITICAL ISSUE.
WHICH IS WHAT IT'S BECOMING
RIGHT NOW.
AND ALSO, AN EDUCATIONAL ISSUE
FOR THE PUBLIC.
THIS THING ABOUT WEAPONS IN OUR
COUNTRY IS DISTURBING.
IT'S IRREFUTABLE.
THERE ARE APPROXIMATELY 300
MILLION OF THEM THAT WE KEEP
REPEATING THIS NUMBER.
WE NEED TO ADDRESS WHO GETS
THEM.
HOW THEY GET THEM.
HOW THE PEOPLE ARE VETTED WHEN
THEY ACQUIRE THEM.
TRAINING ISSUES.
EDUCATION AS TO SAFEGUARDING.
DEALING WITH PEOPLE IN YOUR
HOUSEHOLD WHO, IF THEY HAVE SOME
TYPE OF MENTAL OR EMOTIONAL
HANDICAP, PREVENTING THEM FROM
GETTING ACCESS.
AND SHOULD YOU, IN FACT, EVEN
HAVE THEM IN YOUR HOME IF YOU
HAVE SOMEONE WHO HAS GOT A
MENTAL OR EMOTIONAL ISSUE.
I MEAN, THERE'S A LOT OF TOPICS
TO DISCUSS HERE.
THE HEART-WRENCHING THING IS TO
THINK THAT WE HAVE 20 BABIES
THAT ARE NOW DECEASED.
AND WE'RE ALL WONDERING, IS THIS
SOMETHING THAT WE COULD HAVE
DONE TO HAVE PREVENTED THIS.
AND I'M NOT SURE THERE IS AN
ANSWER THERE.
YOU KNOW, MAYBE -- AND THIS IS
JUST CONJECTURE.
IF WE DIDN'T HAVE GUNS, AND
SOMEONE WAS SO DETERMINED, HOW
DO WE KNOW THEY WOULDN'T GET IN
AN AUTOMOBILE AND DRIVE INTO A
SCHOOL YARD, WHICH, IN FACT, IT
HAPPENED ONE TIME, A COUPLE
DECADES AGO.
YOU KNOW, YOU ALMOST DON'T KNOW
HOW TO RESPOND TO THIS INCIDENT,
BECAUSE IT'S SUCH A SHOCK TO
YOUR SYSTEM.
BUT I DO KNOW THIS.
WE NEED TO DO SOMETHING.
AND WE NEED TO BECOME SENSIBLE
AND ABANDON THESE EXTREME
POSITIONS WE HAVE IN THE NRA AND
THE EXTREME LEFT LIBERAL.
LIVE WITH THE FACT THAT WEAPONS
ARE HERE TO STAY, THESE
FIREARMS, AND HOW DO WE NOW
RESPONSIBLY REGULATE POSSESSION
OF THESE BY INDIVIDUALS.
LET'S START BY KNOWING A LITTLE
BIT MORE ABOUT YOU, OTHER THAN
THE FACT THAT YOU HAVE NO
CRIMINAL HISTORY.
WE SHOULD PSYCHOLOGICALLY
PROFILE EVERY INDIVIDUAL WHO
THINKS THEY NEED A HANDGUN,
ESPECIALLY OF THE TYPE OF THIS
GLOCK OR SIG SAUER.
>> BUT LOU?
>> YES, MA'AM.
>> HOW REALISTIC IS THAT?
AND I UNDERSTAND YOU'RE GIVING
SOLUTIONS, BUT I HAVE COVERED SO
MANY OF THESE TRAGEDIES, AND WE
ALL WRING OUR HANDS, AND ARE
VERY UPSET AND PEOPLE TRY AND
THERE'S A RAGING DEBATE GOING
ON.
AND THEN IT KIND OF GOES AWAY
UNTIL THE NEXT ONE WHEN WE -- IT
ALL COMES BACK AGAIN.
AND I DON'T KNOW THAT ANY OF
THAT IS GOING TO HAPPEN,
HONESTLY.
IF HISTORY IS ANY JUDGE, IT'S
NOT GOING TO HAPPEN.
>> I REALLY THINK THAT THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT NEEDS TO GET
INVOLVED IN THIS WHOLE GUN
ACQUISITION ISSUE.
IT SEEMS TO BE A FEDERAL ISSUE,
BECAUSE IT'S A CONSTITUTIONAL
ISSUE.
IT'S A CONSTITUTIONAL RIGHT THAT
WE'VE DECIDED UPON.
I THINK THE GOVERNMENT SHOULD
TAKE THE PURGATIVE OUT OF THE
HANDS OF THE STATE AND MANDATE
PSYCHOLOGICAL SCREENING FOR
ANYONE THAT WANTS FIREARMS.
ESPECIALLY THESE SPECIFIC TYPES
OF HIGH-CAPACITY AUTOMATIC
PISTOLS THAT WERE MAINLY
PRODUCED FOR THE PURPOSE OF
MILITARY AND LAW ENFORCEMENT.
AND IF YOU REALLY THINK YOU NEED
AN ASSAULT RIFLE -- AND
TRAGICALLY, EVEN THOUGH I DON'T
NECESSARILY AGREE WITH IT, I
UNDERSTAND WHERE PEOPLE OR HOW
PEOPLE GET TO THAT THRESHOLD TO
WHERE THEY DO THINK THEY NEED
THESE WEAPONS.
JUST LOOK AT THE WORLD WE LIVE
IN.
THE TOPICS THAT WE'RE AS MUCH
RATED WITH ON A DAILY BASIS
THROUGH THE MEDIA.
THREAT OF TERRORISM.
SCHOOL SHOOTINGS.
SHOOTINGS IN MALLS.
SHOOTINGS IN MOVIE THEATRES.
THIS STIMULATES OR TRIGGERS
REACTIONS FROM PEOPLE.
>> YEP, YEP, YOU'RE RIGHT.
>> AND LISTEN TO THIS ONE
STATISTIC.
44%, APPROXIMATELY, OF AFTER THE
SHOOTING IN AURORA WENT OUT AND
BOUGHT FIREARMS, BECAUSE THEIR
PERCEPTION WAS THAT THIS IS A
SOLUTION IN KEEPING THEMSELVES
SAFE.
WE NEED TO ADDRESS THIS.
BUT I THINK THE GOVERNMENT NEEDS
TO WRAP THEIR ARMS AROUND THIS,
AND SAY, LISTEN, WE'RE GOING
APPROACH THIS INTELLIGENTLY.
INSTEAD OF APPROACHING IT
POLITICALLY.
>> WELL, IT WILL BE INTERESTING.
THE PRESIDENT HAS CALLED FOR
SORT OF A RESPONSE BUT NO ONE IS
EXACTLY SURE WHAT EXACTLY THAT
DOES MEAN.
LOU POLUMBO NOW RUNS A SECURITY
ORGANIZATION.
THANKS, LOU, APPRECIATE IT.
WANT TO GET BACK TO DEB FEYERICK
AT CNN HEADQUARTERS.
DEB?
>> WE HAVE SOME NEW INFORMATION
THAT'S COMING OUT OF THOSE WHO
WERE KILLED IN THIS TRAGEDY.
THE YOUNGEST WAS 6 YEARS OLD.
THE OLDEST WAS 56.
THAT'S ACCORDING TO INFORMATION
WE LEASED BY THE STATE POLICE.
18 OF THE VICTIMS ARE DESCRIBED
AS FEMALE.
WE KNOW THERE WERE AT LEAST FOUR
EDUCATORS.
THE PRINCIPAL, THE PSYCHOLOGIST,
TWO TEACHERS THAT HAVE SO FAR
BEEN IDENTIFIED.
AND OF COURSE, THE MOTHER OF THE
ALLEGED GUNMAN.
EIGHT OF THE VICTIMS WERE MALE.
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE LEARNING SO
FAR.
AND THE BODIES OF THE CHILDREN
AND OF SOME OF THE ADULTS, THOSE
ARE EXPECTED TO BE RELEASED TO
THE FAMILIES TODAY.
THE BODIES OF THE MOTHER OF THE
ALLEGED GUNMAN AND THE GUNMAN,
THOSE WILL BE HELD UNTIL
TOMORROW.
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE LEARNING SO
FAR.
THE YOUNGEST, 6 YEARS OLD.
OLDEST, 56.
MANY OF THE VICTIMS FIRST
GRADERS.
>> DEB FEYERICK UPDATING US ON
THE SCENE INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
WE HEAR THEY HAVE FINISHED THIS
AFTERNOON WITH THE POSTMORTEMS
ON THE CHILDREN.
AND THEY ARE EXPECTING -- AT
LEAST ACCORDING TO THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER, THAT THE POSTMORTEMS
ON THE SHOOTER AND HIS MOTHER,
THOSE SHOULD BE DONE SOMETIME
TOMORROW MORNING.
WE KNOW THAT, IN FACT,
INVESTIGATORS WILL BE LOOKING AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL FOR
AT LEAST ANOTHER DAY OR MAYBE
EVEN TWO DAYS.
THEY'RE TRYING TO PIECE TOGETHER
REALLY WHAT IS A HORRIFIC
PUZZLE.
WHAT EXACTLY HAPPENED AND WHY
DID IT HAPPEN, TO GIVE US A
BETTER UNDERSTANDING OF HOW IT
WENT DOWN ON FRIDAY.
LET'S GET TO CNN'S JOSH LEVS.
HE'S GOT A VIRTUAL LOOK AT THIS
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
JOSH?
>> YEAH, HI AGAIN.
THERE IS A LOT OF INFORMATION
ABOUT THIS HORROR TODAY,
BOMBARDING YOU.
IT CAN BE A LOT.
I WANT TO TELL YOU, THERE ARE A
FEW VERY SPECIFIC QUESTIONS I
CAN DRILL DOWN FOR YOU THAT WILL
NOT ONLY HELP SHOW WHAT YOU
INVESTIGATORS NEED TO LEARN
HERE, BUT WILL ALSO POTENTIALLY
HAVE REPERCUSSIONS FOR SCHOOLS
AROUND THE COUNTRY IN TERMS OF
SECURITY SYSTEMS.
LET'S ZOOM INTO THIS MAP SO
YOU'RE SEEING IT MORE CLOSELY.
THIS SAY 3-D LOOK AT THIS SCHOOL
ITSELF.
IT HAS 600 STUDENTS TOTAL AND IT
HAS ABOUT 50 MEMBERS OF THE
FACULTY.
NOW, AUTHORITIES HAVE TOLD US,
HAVE SAID THAT THIS ENTIRE THING
IS NOW A CRIME SCENE.
THEY SAID THEY'RE SCOURING THE
ENTIRE BUILDING RIGHT HERE, AND
IN THE WORDS OF POLICE, EACH AND
EVERY CAR IS BEING INVESTIGATED,
AS WELL.
WE DON'T KNOW EXACTLY WHAT
THEY'RE LOOKG FOR.
BUT I WANT TO TRACE YOU THROUGH
A FEW STEPS HERE.
WE NOW KNOW THAT THE DAY BEFORE
THIS HAPPENED, THIS GUNMAN WENT
TO THAT SCHOOL, HAD AN
ALTERCATION WITH FOUR ADULTS.
THE NEXT DAY, CAME BACK, KILLED
THREE OF THEM.
THAT'S ACCORDING TO A LAW
ENFORCEMENT SOURCE WITH
KNOWLEDGE OF THE INVESTIGATION.
SO EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED THERE,
WHETHER IT COULD HAVE PRESENTED
ANY WARNING SIGN, VERY
IMPORTANT.
NEXT THING FOR YOU TO KNOW,
POLICE HAVE SAID TODAY THAT THEY
BELIEVE THEY GOT THE FIRST 911
CALL AROUND 9:30 A.M.
NOW, EACH MINUTE, EACH FRACTION
OF A MINUTE IN A CASE LIKE THIS
IS VERY IMPORTANT.
AND HERE'S WHY.
AS WE UNDERSTAND IT, THE
SECURITY SYSTEM AT THIS SCHOOL
INVOLVING LOCKING DOWN OF DOORS
GETS TURNED ON AT 9:30 A.M.
SO WAS THIS SHOOTER IN THERE
BEFORE OR AFTER THAT SECURITY
SYSTEM WAS TURNED ON?
WELL, THE AUTHORITIES SAY HE DID
HAVE TO BREAK HIS WAY IN.
SO HOW DO YOU DO THAT?
IF THE SECURITY SYSTEM IS ON,
HOW DOES A PERSON WITH MULTIPLE
GUNS BREAK HIS WAY INTO A SCHOOL
WITHOUT ANYONE NOTICING OR
POTENTIALLY SETTING OFF AN
ALARM?
KEY QUESTION RIGHT THERE.
NEXT THING FOR YOU TO KNOW.
THERE ARE SOME SHATTERED WINDOWS
AROUND THIS SCHOOL, WHICH MIGHT
HAVE GUY YOU AN ANSWER TO THE
PREVIOUS QUESTION.
BUT POLICE SAID NOT SO FAST.
WHEN AUTHORITIES WERE CALLED TO
THE SCHOOL YESTERDAY, THEY
NEEDED TO BURST THEIR WAY IN
MULTIPLE UNITS.
AND THAT COULD BE QUITE POSSIBLY
IS THE REASON THAT WINDOWS HAVE
BEEN BURST OPEN.
SO WHERE EXACTLY -- LET'S ZOOM
IN ONE MORE TIME.
WHERE EXACTLY WAS THE GUNMAN IN
THIS PARKING LOT OR AROUND THE
SCHOOL, IN ADVANCE, AS PEOPLE
WERE COMING IN?
HOW EARLY DID HE GET THERE?
WHAT TIME DID HE PHYSICALLY
ENTER THE BUILDING WITH RESPECT
TO WHEN THAT SECURITY SYSTEM WAS
TURNED ON?
AND HOW DID HE DO IT?
ALL OF THESE ARE NEW CENTRAL
QUESTIONS ABOUT THE TIME LINE OF
WHAT HAS HAPPENED, BASED ON WHAT
THE AUTHORITIES ARE TELLING US
TODAY.
>> NOW, WE DO BELIEVE THAT THE
SHOOTING ITSELF TOOK PLACE IN
ONE CORNER OF THE SCHOOL, ONE
GENERAL AREA OF THE SCHOOL.
SO WE DON'T KNOW WHAT OTHER
EVIDENCE THEY MIGHT FIND IN ALL
OF THE CARS AND THROUGHOUT THE
PARKING LOT, THROUGHOUT THE
BUILDING.
WE DO KNOW THEY'RE SCOURING IT
FOR ABSOLUTELY ANYTHING.
SO THOSE ARE SOME OF THE KEY
QUESTIONS WE'RE LOOKING FOR
ANSWERS TO RIGHT NOW.
HOPEFULLY IN THE NEXT FEW DAYS.
>> YEAH, ABSOLUTELY.
ONE THING I'M GOING TO TELL YOU,
WHERE THERE IS CONFLICTING
INFORMATION TO THAT, JOSH, WHEN
WE HEARD OUR FINAL PRESS
CONFERENCE, THERE WAS NO
INFORMATION, WE WERE TOLD BY THE
STATE POLICE, ABOUT A
CONFRONTATION.
SO WE HAVE NOW HEARD BOTH
VERSIONS OF THAT.
SOME SAYING THERE WAS AN
ALTERCATION OR THERE WAS NO
CONFRONTATION.
JOSH LEVS WITH AN UPDATE ON SOME
OF THE QUESTIONS THEY'RE HOPING
TO BE ABLE TO ANSWER AS THIS
INVESTIGATION GOES ALONG.
I THANK YOU FOR THAT.
GOT TO TAKE A SHORT BREAK.
WE'LL CONTINUE OUR COVERAGE OF
THIS TERRIBLE DISASTER, THIS
HORRIFIC MASS SHOOTING AT A
CONNECTICUT ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
RIGHT AFTER THIS BREAK.
WE'LL BE BACK.
>> THEY WERE ASKING WHAT'S GOING
ON.
WE SAID WE DON'T KNOW, OUR JOB
IS TO STAY QUIET.
IT MAY BE A DRILL, IT MAY NOT.
>> YOU DIDN'T KNOW AT THAT
POINT.
>> WE KNEW.
BECAUSE I CALLED THE OFFICE AND
SHE TOLD ME THERE WAS A SHOOTER.
D
FOR LESS THAN THE UPS STORE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I'VE LEARNED THE ONLY WAY TO GET
A HOLIDAY DEAL IS TO CAMP OUT.
YOU KNOW WE'VE BEEN OPEN
ALL NIGHT.
IS THIS A TRICK
TO GET MY SPOT?
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SAVE ON GROUND SHIPPING
AT FEDEX OFFICE.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
SINCE AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL
WAS FOUNDED BACK IN 1894,
THEY'VE BEEN COMMITTED
TO PUTTING CLIENTS FIRST.
HELPING GENERATIONS
THROUGH TOUGH TIMES.
GOOD TIMES.
NEVER TAKING A BAILOUT.
THERE WHEN YOU NEED THEM.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
OVER THE CENTURIES.
THE STRENGTH OF
A GLOBAL FINANCIAL LEADER.
THE HEART OF
A ONE-TO-ONE RELATIONSHIP.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
Bye!
Santa, we made a video for
your trip!
Yeah, you can watch it on your
sleigh!
OK!
Here you go.
Aw, thanks elves.
I also made you a video.
You are so sweet.
But you probably shouldn't watch
it on the sleigh.
Say goodbye to Santa boys!
Bye!
Good bye Santa!
Share videos instantly
with S Beam on the
Galaxy S3 and Note 2.
Available at Best Buy and
Best Buy mobile stores.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
WE'VE BEEN UPDATING YOU WITH THE
VERY LATEST AS WE CONTINUE TO
GET UPDATES FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS.
ONE THING THEY HAVE TOLD US IN
THE LAST HOUR, THERE WAS NO
CONFRONTATION.
THERE WAS SOME WORD THAT IN FACT
THE ALLEGED SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA,
HAD HAD A CONFRONTATION AT THE
SCHOOL IN THE DAYS BEFORE THE
SHOOTING, AND THAT SOMEHOW THAT
WOULD BE LINKED TO THIS
SHOOTING.
WE WERE TOLD IN FACT BY A
LIEUTENANT VANCE WITH THE STATE
POLICE HE HAD NO INFORMATION
ABOUT ANY CONFRONTATION THAT WAS
IN A PRESS CONFERENCE HE WRAPPED
UP ROUGHLY 40 MINUTES AGO OR SO.
ADAM LANZA ALLEGEDLY TARGETED
KINDERGARTNERS AND FIRST
GRADERS, IS WHAT WE NOW KNOW.
UP TO SIX GUNS INVOLVED.
HE ALSO DRESSED UP IN A
MILITARY-STYLE VEST AND BLACK
FATIGUES, AS ALEX DESCRIBED.
AUTHORITIES SAY THEY FOUND THREE
GUNS NEAR LANZA'S BODY IN A
SCHOOL CLASSROOM.
ALL THREE GUNS WERE REGISTERED
TO HIS MOTHER, HIS MOTHER, WHO
WAS ALSO FOUND DEAD IN HER HOME.
INVESTIGATORS RECOVERED THREE
OTHER RIFLES.
IT'S UNCLEAR AT THIS POINT
EXACTLY WHERE THOSE WEAPONS WERE
FOUND.
WE WANT TO GET TO MIKE BOOSHARD,
FORMER ASSISTANT DIRECTOR.
MIKE, WE KNOW YOU SUPERVISED THE
ATF'S RESPONSE A DECADE AGO, A
STORY I COVERED A LOT, THE
WASHINGTON, D.C. BELTWAY SNIPER.
SO UNFORTUNATELY, THIS IS
SOMETHING YOU KNOW A LOT ABOUT.
I WANT YOU TO WALK ME THROUGH
SOME OF THESE WEAPONS.
IN THE PRESS CONFERENCE, THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER SAID THAT
EVERYBODY WAS SHOT WITH THE SAME
RIFLE.
WHICH WOULD BE I GUESS THE
BUSHMASTER.
SO GIVE US SOME MORE INFORMATION
ABOUT THE BUSHMASTER . 223
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE.
THAT CERTAINLY CHANGES THE FACTS
IN THIS CASE.
OBVIOUSLY, THE BUSHMASTER IS
TYPICALLY USED IN A LONGER-RANGE
SHOOTING.
IT HAS MORE ACCURACY FROM A
DISTANCE.
IT'S ODD THAT HE WOULD TAKE THE
LONG GUN INTO THE SCHOOL,
BECAUSE HE COULD DO JUST AS MUCH
DAMAGE WITH THE PISTOLS.
THE ONE ADVANTAGE WITH THE RIFLE
IS TYPICALLY YOU CAN LOAD
30-ROUND MAGAZINES TYPICALLY
DURING SOME OF THESE TACTICAL
SITUATIONS.
THEY'LL STACK THE TWO MAGAZINES,
ONE UPSIDE DOWN, FINISH SHOOTING
30 ROUNDS, PUSH A BUTTON, FLIP
THE OTHER ONE OVER AS QUICKLY AS
YOU CAN TURN IT, AND NOW YOU
HAVE ANOTHER 30 ROUNDS TO SHOOT.
SO THE TACTICS -- WHAT'S ODD
WITH THIS WHOLE THING THAT I
FIND ODD, WE'VE HEARD ABOUT THE
MENTAL HEALTH ISSUE AND THE GUN
ISSUE.
IT'S REALLY A TRIAD.
WHY ARE THESE YOUNG MALES --
WHERE ARE THEY LEARNING THESE
TACTICS, WHERE ARE THEY LEARNING
TO DRESS?
WHERE ARE THEY LEARNING THE
RELOADING TACTICS?
HOW ARE THEY LEARNING TO BRING
THESE TYPE OF WEAPONS AND DO
THESE PREPLANNED ATTACKS?
AND MANY OF THEM ARE LEARNING
FROM VIDEO GAMES OR MOVIES AND
YOU KNOW, I THINK THAT NEEDS TO
BE PART OF THE DISCUSSION,
BECAUSE SOMEBODY WHO IS MENTALLY
UNSTABLE ISN'T NECESSARILY GOING
TO KILL SOMEONE.
SOMEBODY WHO OWNS A GUN ISN'T
NECESSARILY GOING TO KILL
SOMEONE.
BUT WHEN YOU PUT THESE THREE
THINGS TOGETHER, IT CAN BE A
RECIPE FOR DISASTER.
>> YOU KNOW, I THINK YOU'RE
RIGHT.
AND I THINK OUR CULTURE IS
VERY -- IS VERY CONTRADICTORY,
RIGHT, ON ONE HAND WE DID HE CRY
VIOLENCE AND YET OUR MOVIES ARE
SO VIOLENT.
WE TALK ABOUT MENTAL HEALTH, BUT
DON'T NECESSARILY FINANCIALLY
SUPPORT IT.
WE TALK ABOUT GUNS AND THE
AFTERMATH OF EVENTS LIKE THIS,
BUT WE DON'T ACTUALLY DO
ANYTHING ABOUT IT.
SO I THINK YOU'RE