IT'S A PSYCHOLOGICAL EVENT
THAT'S GOING TO TAKE TIME FOR
HEALING.
AND AS LONG AS EVERYONE GETS THE
PROPER HELP, YOU KNOW, IT'S NOT
SOMETHING YOU SHAKE OFF VERY
EASILY AND CERTAINLY NOT FOR
LITTLE PEOPLE.
>> Reporter: I'M LISTENING RIGHT
NOW TO THE TOWN BELLS RINGING
HERE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
I'M NOT SURE WHY THEY ARE
RINGING BUT THIS COMMUNITY HAS
COME TOGETHER TO MOURN TOGETHER
FOR THIS TRAGEDY THAT HAPPENED
AT THE SCHOOL HERE.
WE'VE GOT MUCH MORE AHEAD ON OUR
SPECIAL COVERAGE OF THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTING
WHICH STARTS RIGHT NOW.
>>> AND IT IS ONE OF THE
DEADLIEST SHOOTING RAMPAGES IN
U.S. HISTORY.
ALL MORNING WE'LL BE UPDATING
VICTIMS AND THE INVESTIGATION
HERE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE NOW KNOW THE NAME OF THE
SHOOTER AND DIG INTO WHAT WAS
BEHIND THIS MONSTROUS ACT AND A
SECOND CRIME SCENE TIED TO THE
FIRST.
WHAT INVESTIGATORS FOUND WHEN
THEY WENT TO THE SUSPECT'S
HOUSE.
IT IS SATURDAY, DECEMBER 15th.
I WANT TO SAY GOOD MORNING TO
EVERYONE.
IT'S NOT A GOOD MORNING, IT'S A
DIFFICULT MORNING, BUT WE ARE
SPENDING IT TOGETHER HERE.
I'M JOHN BERMAN.
YOU'RE WATCHING OUR SPECIAL
COVERAGE OF THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL SHOOTING LIVE FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
AND I WANT TO BRING IN MY
COLLEAGUE, ALI VELSHI.
HEY, ALI.
>> Reporter: JOHN, IT'S A SAD
MORNING AND WILL GET SADDER IN A
FEW MOMENTS.
JUST A FEW MOMENTS FROM WHERE WE
ARE STANDING, A PRESS CONFERENCE
IS ABOUT TO BEGIN WHERE THEY ARE
GOING TO RELEASE THE NAMES, WE
THINK, OF MANY OF THE PEOPLE
KILLED.
DAVID ARIOSO OF CNN WAS ONE OF
THE FIRST ON THE SCENE.
DAVID WENT TO THE FIREHOUSE YOU
KEEP HEARING REFERENCES TO WHERE
PARENTS WERE THINKING THEY WERE
GOING TO MEET THEIR KIDS.
DAVID, WHAT HAPPENED YESTERDAY?
>> WELL, BETWEEN THE EARLY
MORNING HOURS, PARENTS WOULD
FILE TOWARDS THIS FIREHOUSE AND
WOULD BASICALLY TRY TO GET A
SENSE OF WHETHER OR NOT THEIR
KIDS, THEIR LOVED ONES WERE
ALIVE.
TOWARD THE EARLY PART OF THE
MORNING, YOU WOULD SEE PARENTS
WALKING OUT TEARY EYED, SHAKEN,
BUT WITH THEIR CHILDREN.
AS THE DAY PROGRESSED, YOU WOULD
SEE PARENTS WALKING IN PAIRS,
WALKING WITH STATE TROOPERS OR
FIREMAN WITHOUT A CHILD M. OF
THE PARENTS WERE BESIDES
THEMSELVES WITH GRIEF.
IT IS JUST ONE OF THOSE THINGS
THAT YOU CAN'T PUT INTO WORDS SO
MUCH.
THAT FIRE STATION THAT BECOMES
SORT OF A WEIGH STATION FOR MANY
OF THE VICTIMS M OF THE VICTIMS
FAMILIES CONTINUES TO BE
POPULATED BY EMERGENCY VEHICLES
IN THE AREA.
BUT THIS IS JUST ONE OF THE
STORIES THAT YOU LOOK FOR WORDS
TO SORT OF DESCRIBE THE
SENTIMENT THAT THE PEOPLE ARE
FEELING HERE AND YOU'RE JUST PUT
AT A LOSS.
>> Reporter: WE ARE STILL
STANDING BY, THE OFFICIALS HAVE
NOT ARRIVED.
WE KNOW THEY ARE HERE, THEY JUST
HAVEN'T GONE TO THE PODIUM YET.
JOHN, YOU WERE AT A LOCATION
WHERE THERE WAS ONE OF A FEW
VIGILS LAST NIGHT.
WE ARE AT THE STAGING AREA WHERE
OFFICIALS ARE GIVING THE PRESS
CONFERENCES.
THE SCHOOL IS OVER THERE BEHIND
US.
THIS IS A SMALL TOWN THAT CAN'T
ACCOMMODATE EVERYONE HERE TO
COVER IT, BUT DAVID WAS THERE
FOR -- HE HAD THE POINT OF
SEEING THESE PARENTS.
THERE ARE MANY PEOPLE, THOSE
PARENTS TOOK THEIR KIDS.
YOU KNOW IF YOU GOT YOUR KID BUT
YOU DON'T KNOW WHO DIDN'T GET
THEIR KID.
THAT'S WHAT WE ARE ABOUT TO FIND
OUT.
THIS IS GOING TO OPEN UP A WHOLE
NEW SET OF WOUNDS.
>> AND THERE ARE FOUR ADULTS WE
DON'T KNOW THE NAMES OF THAT IS
INVOLVED IN THIS.
THIS IS JUST ALL STARTING TO
TRICKLE IN.
WE SPOKE TO FAMILIES YESTERDAY,
CHILDREN WHO WENT THIS
TRANSPIRED WERE CROWDED IN A
CLASSROOM.
I SPOKE TO A THIRD GRADE
8-YEAR-OLD KID BASICALLY TOLD IN
THE BACK BY TEACHERS TO STAY
DOWN, KEEP AWAY.
HER PARENTS ENDED UP RUSHING TO
GET HER AT THE FIRE STATION AND
RECEIVED THIS AUTOMATED MESSAGE
NOT KNOWING IF THEIR CHILDREN
WERE ALIVE OR DEAD.
NOT EVEN REALLY KNOWING WHICH
SCHOOL THE SHOOTING HAD TAKEN
PLACE IN.
THE WHOLE COMMUNITY WAS FLOCKING
TO SCHOOLS IN AND AROUND THE
REGION NOT KNOWING WHAT
TRANSPIRED.
I DON'T THINK MANY OF US THOUGHT
THAT IT COULD HAVE BEEN THIS
BAD.
AGAIN, JUST WATCHING SOME OF
THESE PARENTS WHACK UP THAT HILL
YESTERDAY, THOSE THAT WERE
WILLING TO SPEAK WITH US WE
COULD ONLY DO SO IN GASPS AND
BREATHS.
MOST DIDN'T WANT TO FOR
UNDERSTANDABLE REASONS.
>> Reporter: JOHN, MANY OF THE
PARENTS ARRIVED AT THE SCENE NOT
KNOWING, NOT KNOWING THAT THEIR
KIDS MAY NOT SHOW UP.
THE INITIAL REPORTS AS YOU
RECALL YESTERDAY MORNING WAS
THEY CALLED FOR TWO AMBULANCES.
THIS DID NOT LOOK LIKE WHAT IT
WAS GOING TO END UP BEING.
JOHN?
>> THAT'S SO TRUE, ALI.
I CAN'T IMAGINE GOING THROUGH
SOMETHING LIKE THAT, BUT WE
SHOULD SAY RIGHT NOW THIS
COMMUNITY IS GOING THROUGH IT
TOGETHER.
I'M STANDING OUTSIDE ST. ROSE OF
LIMA CATHOLIC CHURCH WHERE LAST
NIGHT THERE WAS A VIGIL.
ABOUT 1,000 PEOPLE INSIDE AND
OUTSIDE HERE TO MOURN TOGETHER,
TO GRIEVE TOGETHER.
WE WALKED INSIDE THE CHURCH A
LITTLE WHILE AGO.
THERE ARE TWO BULLETIN BOARDS
WHERE PEOPLE HAVE ALREADY
STARTED POSTING MESSAGES OF
SOLIDARITY, GRIEF AND
REMEMBRANCE.
THERE ARE THE VICTIMS, 20
CHILDREN, AGES 5 TO 10.
WE ARE AWAITING A NEWS
CONFERENCE NOW WHERE WE EXPECT
WE WILL LEARN THE NAMES OF THESE
VICTIMS AS WELL AS SIX ADULTS
WHO WERE KILLED AT THAT SCHOOL.
WE WANT TO LEARN SO MUCH MORE
ABOUT WHAT WAS GOING ON, SO MANY
PEOPLE AFFECTED BY THIS.
I SPOKE TO THE PARENT OF A
SURVIVOR A SHORT WHILE AGO WHO
IS TALKING TO HIS DAUGHTER, AN
8-YEAR-OLD GIRL, A THIRD GRADER
WHO SURVIVED THE SHOOTING.
SHE WAS LOCKED IN A CLOSET IN
HER CLASSROOM AS IT WAS GOING
ON.
THEN SHE WAS ONE OF THE FIRST
PEOPLE BROUGHT TO THE FIREHOUSE.
SHE HAS A 10-YEAR-OLD BROTHER AT
ANOTHER SCHOOL.
THIS 8-YEAR-OLD THIRD BADER AND
10-YEAR-OLD TELLING THEIR FATHER
THEY DON'T WANT TO GO BACK TO
SCHOOL ON MONDAY.
THAT'S SO UNDERSTANDABLE.
SO MANY PEOPLE TRYING TO WORK
THROUGH THIS, BUT AS I SAID,
THIS TOWN OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, 60 MILES OUTSIDE OF
NEW YORK CITY RIGHT NOW WORKING
THROUGH IT TOGETHER.
ALI?
>> Reporter: ONE OF THE THINGS
THAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN, WE ARE
GOING TO HEAR THE NAMES.
THERE'S A LOT OF EFFORT TO FIND
OUT WHO THE VICTIMS WERE.
POLICE ARE SAYING VERY CLEARLY,
THIS WAS A REAL DIFFICULT TASK
TO IDENTIFY.
THEY HAD TENTATIVE
IDENTIFICATIONS ON EVERYBODY BY
LAST NIGHT.
THEY WANTED POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATIONS AND WERE NOT
GOING TO LET THEIR KIDS, THEY
WERE NOT GOING TO LET THE
PARENTS INTO THE SCHOOL TO SEE
THEIR KIDS IN THAT SITUATION.
SO WE ARE WAITING FOR THAT
MOMENTARILY.
THE PARENTS KNOW WHO THEIR KIDS
ARE, OBVIOUSLY, THE CHILDREN
DIDN'T COME HOME LAST NIGHT.
THE BODIES ARE STILL IN THE
BUILDING, AND THAT'S AN ACTIVE
CRIME SCENE, BUT THERE'S ALSO
ANOTHER ACTIVE CRIME SCENE IN
THIS CITY, JOHN.
>> Reporter: THE ONE NAME POLICE
ALREADY RELEASED IS ADAM LANZA.
HE CARRIED OUT THE ATTACK ON THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WHEN THEY ARRIVED AT HIS HOME,
THEY MADE A STARTLING DISCOVERY.
MARY SNOW IS AT LANZA'S HOME.
MARY, WHAT DID POLICE FIND
THERE?
>> Reporter: JOHN, POLICE FOUND
THE BODY OF LANZA'S MOTHER,
NANCY LANZA.
IT IS BELIEVED HE LIVED IN A
HOME WITH HIS MOTHER IN A HOME
BEHIND ME.
POLICE HAVE BLOCKED OFF THIS
AREA.
THIS WAS REALLY COVERED BY
S.W.A.T. TEAMS YESTERDAY FOR
SEVERAL HOURS DURING THE DAY TO
THE POINT OF WHERE RESIDENTS HAD
BEEN EVACUATED FOR SEVERAL
HOURS.
AND BETWEEN RESIDENTS AND
FRIENDS, FORMER CLASSMATES, THEY
ARE PIECING TOGETHER MORE
INFORMATION ABOUT ADAM LANDA.
AND ONE OF THE PIECES OF THE
INFORMATION AND THE PROFILE OF
HIM, SUSAN CANDIOTTI WAS
REPORTING THAT A LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIAL SAID THAT A FAMILY
MEMBER TOLD INVESTIGATORS THAT
HE HAD A FORM OF AUTISM.
A FORMER CLASSMATE DESCRIBED HIM
AS A STUDENT WHO WAS VERY
BRIGHT, BUT ALSO VERY REMOTE.
TAKE A LISTEN TO WHAT ONE OF HIS
FORMER CLASSMATES HAD TO SAY
LAST NIGHT.
>> HE WAS REALLY QUIET.
HE KEPT TO HIMSELF.
I MEAN, HE WAS A LITTLE FIDGETY,
A LITTLE UNEASY SOMETIMES IF YOU
WERE TO LOOK AT HIM.
I THINK HE WAS JUST SOCIALLY NOT
REALLY INTO GOING OUT THERE TO
MAKE AS MANY FRIENDS AS EVERYONE
WAS REALLY DOING IN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AND MIDDLE SCHOOL.
HE WAS JUST, HE PREFERRED TO
STAY TO HIMSELF.
>> Reporter: OF COURSE, THAT WAS
A FORMER CLASSMATE FROM MANY
YEARS AGO.
ONE OF THE NEIGHBORS I SPOKE TO
YESTERDAY WOULD ONLY DESCRIBE
HIM AS BEING SOMEONE THAT SHE
THOUGHT WAS TROUBLED.
AND OTHER RESIDENTS HAD
DESCRIBED HIM AS BEING A
DIFFERE
DIFFERENT, DIFFERENT AND ONE
DESCRIPTION AS A LITTLE OFF.
>> WE KNOW HE LIVED WITH HIS
MOTHER HERE IN NEWTOWN.
WHAT ABOUT THE WEAPONS THAT WERE
USED IN THIS SHOOTING, MARY?
WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT THEM?
WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT WHERE HE
MAY HAVE PICKED THEM UP OR
GOTTEN THEM?
>> Reporter: CNN HAS LEARNED
THAT THE WEAPONS WERE LEGALLY
PURCHASED AND LEGALLY PURCHASED
BY HIS MOTHER.
WHAT WE FOUND OUT IS TWO
HANDGUNS WERE AT THE SCENE AND A
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE WAS FOUND IN
A CAR OUTSIDE THE SCHOOL.
SO THOSE THREE WEAPONS WE HAVE
BEEN TOLD, WE HAVE BEEN
REPORTING THAT THEY WERE LEGALLY
PURCHASED.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
TWO PISTOLS, A SIG SAUER AND A
GLAUCOMA PISTOL.
MARY SNOW, THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
THAT.
THERE ARE SO MANY QUESTIONS
ABOUT THIS INVESTIGATION RIGHT
NOW.
NIFS HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY, LATE
LAST NIGHT.
HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY, WAS THE
SITE OF AN ACTIVE SCENE.
BOMB SQUAD MEMBERS, THE FBI
THERE, WHY?
THEY WERE LOOKING AT THE
APARTMENT OF 24-YEAR-OLD RYAN
LANZA.
APPARENTLY ADAM LANZA HAD HIS
BROTHER'S I.D. ON HIM.
HIS I.D. WAS ON THE BODY OF ADAM
LANZA.
SO THEY WENT TO ASK THE BROTHER
SOME QUESTIONS AND WERE TALKING
TO HIM.
THEY ALSO REMOVED MATERIALS FROM
THAT APARTMENT.
JUST ONE OF THE ASPECTS OF THE
CONFUSION YESTERDAY DURING THIS
INVESTIGATION.
ALI?
>> Reporter: THAT DID ADD A LOT
OF CONFUSION TO THIS WHOLE
EPISODE.
THEY TOOK HIM INTO CUSTODY, THE
BROTHER, AND THEY WERE
INTERVIEWING THE FATHER.
IT HAS NOW BEEN ALMOST 24 HOURS
SINCE THE UNIMAGINABLE HAPPENED
HERE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
IT ALL STARTED WHEN A GUNMAN
ENTERED THROUGH THE DOORS OF
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE ARE AWAITING A PRESS
CONFERENCE, YOU'RE LOOKING AT
THAT RIGHT NOW.
IT HAS NOT BEGUN, BUT I DO WANT
TO GIVE THOSE OF YOU WHO HAVE
JOINED US A SENSE OF WHAT
HAPPENED.
TOM FOREMAN WALKS US THROUGH
WHAT HAPPENED YESTERDAY MORNING
MINUTE BY MINUTE.
>> THIS IS WHAT WE KNOW AT THIS
POINT ABOUT THE TIMELINE OF THE
SHOOTING REPORTED BY LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS AND
WITNESSES AND THE LAYOUT OF THE
SCHOOL AS BEST WE CAN PIECE IT
ALL TOGETHER.
9:30 IN THE MORNING, CLASSES HAD
BEEN UNDERWAY FOR A HALF HOUR.
MORE THAN 600 STUDENTS AND
APPROXIMATELY 50 FACULTY MEMBERS
INSIDE THE BUILDING.
IN ADDITION TO THAT THERE'S A
MEETING JUST CONVENED BY SOME OF
THE SCHOOL OFFICIALS INCLUDING
THE PRINCIPAL IN A ROOM
SOMEWHERE RIGHT UP HERE, ABOUT
SEVEN OF THEM ALL GATHERED IN
ONE ROOM.
ABOUT 9:40, TEN MINUTES LATER,
AS BECK WE CAN MAKE IT OUT,
THAT'S WHEN THE GUNMAN APPEARS
TO HAVE ENTERED THE BUILDING.
HOW?
WE DON'T KNOW.
THEY HAD A NEW SECURITY SYSTEM
RIGHT UP HERE THAT MIGHT HAVE
KEPT HIM OUT, NOT SURE WHAT
HAPPENED WITH THAT.
POLICE PUT A LOT OF TIME LOOKING
AT A CAR PARKED RIGHT OUT HERE
IN THE FIRE LANE SUGGESTING THAT
IF THAT WERE HIS CAR, THAT IN
FACT HE MAY HAVE INDEED COME
RIGHT THROUGH THE FRONT DOOR
HERE INTO THE SCHOOL.
PEOPLE THROUGHOUT THE BUILDING
AT THAT POINT START SAYING THAT
THEY ARE HEARING SHOTS.
9:41, THE CALLS START GOING IN
TO 911 AT THAT POINT.
AND THE PRINCIPAL, THE VICE
PRINCIPAL AND THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST ALL GOING TOWARD
THE GUNFIRE NOW THE HALLWAY
ACCORDING TO A WITNESS.
ONLY THE VICE PRINCIPAL RETURNS
AND IS WOUNDED.
THERE'S MUCH SHOUTING.
THERE ARE MANY, MANY SHOTS OUT
THERE.
EVERYONE SAYS THEY HEAR IT.
AUTHORITIES SAY THE SHOOTING
ITSELF HAPPENED IN A RELATIVELY
SHORT PERIOD OF TIME AND THEY
SAY THE GUNMAN DOES NOT ROAM
AROUND BUT GENERALLY STAYS IN
THIS AREA.
IN FACT, THEY SAY ALL THE
SHOOTING HAPPENED IN JUST TWO
ROOMS.
9:45, TEACHERS THROUGHOUT THIS
BUILDING ARE TRYING TO PROTECT
STUDENTS.
AND IN SOME CASES, THE STUDENTS
SAID THEY HELPED THEM HIDE AND
IN OTHERS THEY SEEM LIKE THE
TEACHERS TRIED TO GET THEM OUT
OF THE BUILDING.
THE BOTTOM LINE IS IN THIS
PICTURE FROM THE NEWTOWN B,
THERE WAS AN EFFORT TO GET THE
STUDENTS OUT.
THAT'S DIFFICULT BECAUSE YOU
HAVE HUNDREDS OF KIDS HERE
TRAUMATIZED AND VERY UPSET.
9:50, BY THIS TIME FOR SURE,
AGAIN, WE ARE NOT SURE OF THE
TIMELINE, IT'S MURKY, BUT THE
GUNMAN SOMEWHERE IN THIS PROCESS
HAS DIED.
POLICE OFFICERS SAY NO OFFICER
FIRED A SHOT SO IT IS BELIEVED
HE SHOT HIMSELF, BUT THIS WE DO
KNOW.
AS OFFICERS ARRIVED ON THE SCENE
FROM STATE AND LOCAL POLICE,
THEY SECURED THE ENTIRE BUILDING
AND THEY SPREAD OUT THROUGH IT
TRYING TO MAKE SURE THAT THERE
ARE NO OTHER GUNMEN AND TRYING
TO FIND ALL THE POCKETS OF
CHILDREN HIDING WITHIN THIS
BUILDING.
AT THAT POINT THEY START
ESCORTING THEM OUT OF THE
BUILDING AS WELL.
A DIFFICULT, DIFFICULT TIME.
AND THIS TIMELINE IS WHAT THE
INVESTIGATORS ARE GOING TO HAVE
TO BUILD UPON IN THE COMING
WEEKS TO CLARIFY, TO MAKE SURE
WE KNOW EXACTLY WHEN THINGS
HAPPENED AND HOW.
>> Reporter: ALL THAT WE KNOW,
ALL THE DETAIL TOM FOREMAN
BRINGS US, THERE'S SO MUCH WE
DON'T KNOW.
ON THE RIGHT SIDE OF YOUR
SCREEN, WE ARE PREPARING FOR A
PRESS CONFERENCE.
NEW SECURITY MEASURES WERE JUST
IMPLEMENTED AT THE SCHOOL.
WE DON'T KNOW EXACTLY WHY THE
SCHOOL WAS TARGETED BY THIS
GUNMAN JUST YET.
WE ARE HOPING TO GET THOSE
ANSWERS.
THE ANSWERS TO THOSE QUESTIONS
WE HOPE TO GET FAIRLY SOON.
WHAT WE EXPECT TO HAPPEN RIGHT
NOW IS TO GET THE NAMES, THE
IDENTITIES OF SOME OF THE
PEOPLE.
LET'S CHECK IN NOW WITH NICK
VALENCIA IN ATLANTA.
WE KNOW THE IDENTITY OF TWO OF
THE ADULTS WHO WERE KILLED.
THE SCHOOL PRINCIPAL AND THE
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST, THE NAMES
OF THE FOUR OTHER ADULTS HAVE
JUST BEEN RELEASED.
WHAT DO WE SNOW IN.
>> WE ARE STILL STANDING BY TO
HEAR MORE ABOUT THE VICTIMS, 26
PARISHED IN ALL YESTERDAY AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
TWO CONFIRMED NAMES, TWO VICTIMS
WE HAVE CONFIRMED SO FAR, ALI,
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, A PRINCIPAL AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
SINCE 2010.
DESCRIBED AS A TEACHER'S
TEACHER.
SOMEBODY YOU WOULD WANT TEACHING
YOUR CHILDREN.
IN FACT, SHE WAS NOT DONE WITH
HER OWN EDUCATION AND JUST
ENTERED A PH.D. PROGRAM
CONTINUING ON WITH HER
EDUCATION.
SHE SPENT HER CAREER RISING
THROUGH THE RANKS OF CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL SYSTEM, SPENDING A LOT OF
TIME IN THE SMALL COMMUNITIES
WORKING SAT VARIOUS COMMUNITY
SCHOOLS AND HIGH SCHOOLS.
THOSE WHO REMEMBER HER SAY SHE
CREATED THIS WONDERFUL
ENVIRONMENT TO MAKE PEOPLE FEEL
EMBRACED, ACCEPTED, IMPORTANT
AND ABOVE ALL SECURE.
SHE LEAVES BEHIND TWO DAUGHTERS
AND THREE STEP-DAUGHTERS.
JUST A TERRIBLE, TERRIBLE
SITUATION.
REMEMBERED FOR HER ENTHUSIASM
AND WONDERFUL SMILE.
YOU CAN SEE THAT THERE.
NOW ANOTHER VICTIM AT THE SCHOOL
WHO PARISHED WAS THE SCHOOL'S
PSYCHOLOGIST.
SHE'S BEING NAMED AS MARY
SHERLOCK, 56 YEARS OLD.
SHE WAS A REALLY INSTRUMENTAL
PART OF THE FABRIC OF THAT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND PART OF
THE CRISIS AND INTERVENTION
PROGRAM AT THE SCHOOL.
A LOT OF PEOPLE WOULD TURN TO
HER IN A TIME LIKE THIS, BUT
SHE'S NO LONGER WITH US.
SHE WAS AN EXPERT IN PSYCHOLOGY
AND HAD HER MASTER'S DEGREE.
SHE WORKED A LOT IN THE
COMMUNITY WITH DISABLED ADULTS
IN THE SURROUNDING COMMUNITY.
LEAVES BEHIND TWO DAUGHTERS AND
A HUSBAND NAMED BILL OF 31
YEARS.
A VERY SAD SITUATION.
TWO NAMES OF THE VICTIMS OF THE
SIX ADULTS THAT WERE SHOT
YESTERDAY IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
ALI?
>> Reporter: FOUR OTHER ADULTS
SHOT HERE, ADULTS DEDICATED TO
MAKING THE LIVES OF THOSE
CHILDREN BETTER.
WE'LL MAKE SURE IN ADDITION TO
THE NAMES OF THE 20 CHILDREN
WE'LL BRING YOU THE NAMES OF THE
FOUR ADULTS WE DON'T KNOW.
ALSO THE GUNMAN'S MOTHER, NANCY
LAN
LANZA, A VICTIM AT THE HOME SHE
SHARED WITH ADAM LANZA.
THE NEWS CONFERENCE HAS NOT
BEGUN YET BUT THERE'S SUCH A
PACK OF PEOPLE BEHIND AND IN
FRONT OF US HERE.
WE ARE EXPECTING AND WAITING FOR
IMPORTANT NEWS THERE WITH THE
NAMES OF THOSE KILLED.
>>> THE AUTHORITIES HERE IN
NEWTOWN HAVE BEEN SO
CONSCIENTIOUS ABOUT KEEPING
EVERYONE UPDATED ON WHAT THEY
KNOW.
THEY HELD A SERIES OF PRESS
CONFERENCES YESTERDAY INTO THE
EVENING AND TOLD US THEY WOULD
BE TALKING TO US AGAIN HERE IN
NEWTON.
THAT'S WHAT WE ARE WAITING ON
HERE.
YOU CAN SEE PEOPLE GATHERING IN
THE PICTURE.
WE DON'T HAVE THE OFFICIALS UP
YET AT THE PODIUM.
AMONG THE THINGS WE EXPECT THEM
TO DISCUSS, PERHAPS THE NAMES OF
SOME OF THE VICTIMS, AGES 5 TO
10 YEARS OLD.
SOME 20 KIDS.
ALSO THE SIX ADULTS.
WE HEARD SOME ABOUT THEM RIGHT
NOW INCLUDING THE PRINCIPAL AND
THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST.
ALSO THE MOTHER OF THE ALLEGED
SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA, WAS KILLED.
NOT ON LOCATION HERE BUT
APPARENTLY IN THIS HOME, HER
HOME.
THIS HOUR WE'LL TALK TO A FRIEND
OF PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG,
BUT FIRST, ALI, WE'LL TALK ABOUT
THE SITUATION THERE.
WHEN DO WE EXPECT, I CAN'T SEE
RIGHT NOW THAT PICTURE RIGHT
NOW, HOW CLOSE WE ARE TO THAT --
>> Reporter: I'LL GIVE YOU A
SENSE OF IT.
I'LL GIVE YOU A SENSE OF IT.
WE KNOW THE POLICE OFFICERS ARE
HERE.
WE KNOW THAT THE STATE POLICE
REPRESENTATIVES ARE HERE.
THEY WERE HERE A FEW MINUTES
AGO.
I THINK THEY ARE REALLY TRYING,
YOU JUST MENTIONED THEY ARE
REALLY WORKING VERY HARD TO GET
INFORMATION OUT AS QUICKLY AS
POSSIBLE.
AND QUESTIONS THAT THEY HAVE NOT
BEEN ABLE TO ANSWER, THEY KEEP
TELLING US, WE'LL BE BACK IN AN
HOUR WITH MORE INFORMATION.
THEY DID THAT UNTIL 8:00 P.M.
LAST NIGHT, 8:00 P.M. EASTERN
THEY SAID WE'LL LET YOU, THE
MEDIA, TAKE A BREAK AND GET
REST.
WE ARE GOING TO LET OUR PEOPLE
GET SOME REST BUT THE CRIME
SCENES WERE NOT GOING TO BE,
THERE'S GOING TO BE NO REST.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER WAS AT THE
SCHOOL ALL NIGHT.
THEY WERE PROCESSING THE BODIES,
BUT THE TERRIBLE INCIDENT OF THE
PARENTS WHO KNEW THEIR KIDS
DIDN'T COME HOME, THEY WERE NOT
ALLOWED INTO THE SCHOOL.
SO THEY HAD TENTATIVE
IDENTIFICATIONS ON ALL THE
BODIES AND THEN GOT POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATIONS FROM THE
PARENTS.
THEY WERE NOT GOING TO RELEASE
ANY NAMES UNTIL THEY HAD
POSITIVE IDENTIFICATION ON
EVERYBODY.
NOW WHERE WE ARE, WE ARE AT
TREADWELL MEMORIAL PARK WITH A
SOCCER AND FOOTBALL FIELD AND A
BASEBALL DIAMOND NEXT TO IT.
THE SCHOOL IS OVER THERE.
THE AUTHORITIES MADE SURE TO
KNOW THERE WAS GLOBAL INTEREST
IN THIS STORY AND IMPORTANTLY,
THIS IS OBVIOUSLY A STORY THAT
MOVES EVERYBODY.
AND THAT'S WHY THEY SET US UP
OVER HERE.
YOU'RE IN A DIFFERENT LOCATION
AT ONE OF THE PLACES WHERE THERE
WAS A VIGIL DOWNTOWN.
A LOT OF ACTIVITY IN THIS SMALL
TOWN, JOHN.
>> Reporter: ABSOLUTELY.
ONE OF THE VICTIMS WE KNOW ABOUT
WHAT YOU SAY THE PRINCIPAL OF
THE SCHOOL, DAWN HOCHSPRUNG
DESCRIBED AS A, QUOTE, TOUGH
LADY IN THE RIGHT SORT OF SENSE.
WORKING ON SCHOOL SECURITY, SHE
WAS IDOLIZED BAY LOT OF PEOPLE
IN THE COMMUNITY.
A 47-YEAR-OLD MOTHER OF TWO
DAUGHTERS, THREE STEP-DAUGHTERS.
WHEN HER LIFE CAME TO A TRAGIC
END IN THE SCHOOL THAT SHE WAS
AT SINCE 2010.
SHE HAD BEEN AN ADMINISTRATOR
FOR TEN YEARS.
PARENTS SAID SHE WAS CREATIVE
AND TALKED ABOUT THE FUN THINGS
THEY DID.
I HEARD ABOUT DRESS-UP DAYS SHE
WAS LEADING.
SHE WAS ONE OF 15 EDUCATORS IN A
DOCTOR PROGRAM AT THE SAGE
COLLEGE HERE IN NEW YORK.
THE DEAN THERE, DR. LAURA QUIGLY
JOINS ME.
WHAT KIND OF IMPRESSION DID THIS
PRINCIPAL, DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, GIVE
TO YOU?
WHAT KIND OF IMPRESSION DID SHE
MAKE ON YOUR STUDENTS?
>> I MET HER FIRST OF ALL WHEN I
WELCOMED THE STUDENTS TO THE
CAMPUS LAST SUMMER.
OF THE 16 CANDIDATES ACCEPTED
INTO THE DOCTORATE PROGRAM THIS
YEAR, I REALLY HONESTLY HAVE TO
SAY SHE WAS THE ONE PERSON WHO
LEFT AN INDELIBLE MARK ON ME
BECAUSE I WAS SO IMPRESSED BY
HER COMMENTS, HER DEDICATION TO
HER SMALL COMMUNITY IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
HER FELLOW CLASSMATES WERE JUST
AMAZED SHE WAS TRAVELING FROM
CONNECTICUT UP TO THE CAPITOL
REGION OF NEW YORK TO PURSUE HER
DOCTORATE IN EDUCATIONAL
LEADERSHIP.
SHE SPOKE ABOUT HOW SHE TRULY
BELIEVED THAT HER ROLE IN
EDUCATION WAS TO CREATE SUCH
LEADERS OF THE ELEMENTARY
CHILDREN WITH WHOM SHE SERVED.
SHE HAD AN INFECTIOUS SMILE AND
SHE WAS ALWAYS SMILING.
I THINK THAT'S A REASON WHY I
REMEMBER HER SO DEARLY.
>> Reporter: LORI, IT IS NOT
OFTEN YOU HEAR PEOPLE IN A TOWN,
PARENTS AND TEACHERS AND KIDS
TALK ABOUT A PRINCIPAL WITH SUCH
REVERENCE.
DID SHE SHARE ANYTHING ABOUT HER
SCHOOL AND STUDENTS BACK HERE IN
CONNECTICUT?
>> WELL, IN HER CLASSES I KNOW
IN TALKING WITH SOME OF HER
FELLOW STUDENTS AND WITH THE
PROFESSORS, SHE DID TALK ABOUT
HOW SHE TRULY DID BELIEVE IN
CREATING AN ENVIRONMENT WHERE
CHILDREN FELT SAFE, WHERE
CHILDREN TREATED EACH OTHER WITH
RESPECT, WHERE IT WAS AN
ENVIRONMENT THAT TRULY FELT
CARE.
AND I THINK THAT'S REALLY THE
TRAGIC IRONY OF THIS ENTIRE
SITUATION.
WE OPENED UP AN ONLINE
DISCUSSION FORMAT FOR OUR
DOCTORATE CANDIDATES TO TALK TO
ONE ANOTHER.
ALL THE CANDIDATES IN THE
PROGRAM ARE CURRENT LEADERS,
PRINCIPALS, ASSISTANT PRINCIPALS
AND SUPERINTENDENTS, IT IS
HITTING THEM HARD.
BUT THEY HAVE TO GO TO BACK TO
WORK ON MONDAY AND TALK TO THEIR
FACULTY AND STAFF AND TALK TO
THEM, HOW DO THEY TALK TO THEIR
CHILDREN IN THEIR SCHOOLS ABOUT
THIS SITUATION?
>> Reporter: AND HOW DO WE MAKE
AN ENVIRONMENT THAT'S SAFE.
YOU HAVE SEEN SO MANY SCHOOL
SHOOTINGS SINCE COLUMBINE WAY
BACK IN THE 1990s.
AS A PROFESSIONAL EDUCATOR THAT
WORKS WITH PARENTS, TEACHERS,
ADMINISTRATORS, LET ME FIRST ASK
YOU THIS, WHAT KIND OF QUESTIONS
SHOULD WE BE ASKING IN THE FACE
OF THIS REPEATED SCHOOL
VIOLENCE?
>> WELL, I THINK WE HAVE TO SORT
OF ASK OURSELVES BEYOND THE
SCHOOL ENVIRONMENT, FIRST OF
ALL, I REALLY DO BELIEVE IN OUR
SCHOOL ENVIRONMENTS.
OUR PROFESSIONALS ARE DEDICATED.
THEIR NUMBER ONE FOCUS IS THE
EDUCATION AND THE WELL-BEING OF
YOUNG CHILDREN.
BUT I THINK BEYOND THAT IN OUR
SOCIETY, I THINK MAYBE WE HAVE
TO QUESTION, YOU KNOW, WHAT IS
THE IMPACT OF MEDIA, WHAT'S THE
IMPACT OF SOCIAL MEDIA?
WHAT'S THE IMPACT OF THE LACK OF
APPROPRIATE GUN CONTROL LAWS?
I HEAR YOU TALKING ABOUT THAT
AND WE CONTINUE TO TALK ABOUT
THAT AFTER EVERY TRAGIC EVENT,
BUT WHERE IS THE ACTION AS A
RESULT OF ALL THIS TALK?
>> Reporter: LORI, THANK YOU SO
MUCH FOR JOINING US.
THESE ARE THE QUESTIONS THAT
NEED TO BE ASKED, THE
DISCUSSIONS THAT HAVE TO HAPPEN
IN THE DAYS AND WEEKS AHEAD.
ALI?
>> Reporter: ALL RIGHT, JOHN, I
WANT TO BRING IN FORMER FBI
ASSISTANT DIRECTOR TOM FUENTES,
ALSO A CNN CONTRIBUTOR.
TOM, I WANT TO ASK YOU
SOMETHING, WE'LL BE HEARING FROM
THE POLICE, WE MAY OR MAY NOT
GET ALL OF THE NAMES OF THE
VICTIMS.
I DON'T KNOW WHY WE WOULDN'T,
BUT LAST NIGHT YOU WOULD HAVE
KNOWN WHO ALL THE VICTIMS WERE.
THE PARENTS WOULD HAVE KNOWN,
OBVIOUSLY, THEIR PARENTS DIDN'T
COME HOME.
AND THERE ARE FOUR ADULTS.
EVERYBODY KNEW THAT.
THEY WILL NOT GIVE OUT THE
INFORMATION, THEY WILL NOT GIVE
OUT THE NAMES UNTIL EVERYBODY IS
POSITIVELY IDENTIFIED.
TELL ME ABOUT THAT PROCESS.
THE BODIES STAYED IN THE SCHOOL
ALL NIGHT.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
MORE ON THE PROCESS NOW IS
REALLY LOOKING AT THE MORE
HORRIFIC ASPECT OF THIS, WHERE
WERE THE CHILDREN AS THEY WERE
BEING SHOT?
WHERE WAS THE SHOOTER?
HOW CLOSE WAS HE?
SO THAT'S PART OF THE QUESTION
OF WHY THE BODIES HAVE BEEN IN
THE BUILDING ALL NIGHT WHILE
THEY WERE WORKING ON THIS.
>> Reporter: AND THEY WOULD
TYPICALLY NOT LET THE PARENT
INTO AN ACTIVE CRIME SCENE.
WHEN THEY SAY THEY NEED POSITIVE
IDENTITIES TO THE BODIES, WHAT
DOES THAT MEAN.
>> THEY DON'T WANT PARENTS
CONTAMINATING THE SCENE AND
BEING OVERCOME WITH GRIEF AND
GRABBING THEIR CHILDREN OR
HAVING A WORSE SITUATION INSIDE
THE SCHOOL, INSIDE THE CRIME
SCENE.
SO THAT WOULD BE THE REASON FOR
THE SECURITY AS THEY ARE TRYING
TO METHODICALLY ENSURE THEY HAVE
FIGURED OUT EXACTLY WHAT
HAPPENED TO EACH INDIVIDUAL
CHILD, WHAT THE SHOOTER DID,
WHERE THE VICTIMS WERE AND THEN,
OF COURSE, THE IDENTIFICATION
PROCESS THAT GOES WITH THAT.
>> Reporter: TOM, THERE'S A
SECOND CRIME SCENE, I WAS THERE
LAST NIGHT, MARY SNOW IS THERE
NOW, THE HOME OF THE SHOOTER.
THEY CLOSED OFF THE ENTIRE ROAD
AND TOLD FAMILIES TO LEAVE AND
NOT COME BACK.
WHAT DO THEY DO IN A SCENE LIKE
THAT?
>> WELL N THAT SITUATION THEY
WEREN'T SURE IF BEFORE HE WENT
TO THE SCHOOL TO SHOOT WHETHER
HE HAD SET UP BOBBY TRAPS OR HAD
EXPLOSIVES OR MATERIAL AT THE
HOUSE.
THAT'S WHY THEY EVACUATED
NEIGHBORS JUST TO MAKE SURE THAT
THERE WAS NOT SOME GREATER
DANGER TO THE COMMUNITY THAT
WOULD HAVE COME FROM THAT HOUSE.
SO THEY WANTED TO MAKE SURE THAT
THAT SCENE WAS SECURE.
AND THEN, OF COURSE, THEY GO IN
AND DETERMINE THAT THERE'S
ANOTHER BODY THERE, HIS MOTHER.
AND THEY HAVE TO PROCESS THAT.
SO THERE'S WORK TO BE DONE
THERE, BUT THEY HAVE TO BE,
AGAIN, VERY METHODICAL THAT
THERE WEREN'T HARMFUL MATERIALS
PLACED IN THERE TO AFFECT THE
NEIGHBORING HOUSES AND THE
INVESTIGATORS THEMSELVES AS THEY
ARE WORKING.
>> Reporter: TOM, THIS IS A
SMALL TOWN.
AS SOON AS THIS HAPPENED THEY
HAD A MUTUAL AID AGREEMENT.
DANBURY HAS A BIGGER POLICE
FORCE AND STATE POLICE WERE IN
HERE.
JOHN BERMAN SAID THE AUTHORITIES
DID A FANTASTIC JOB OF
SHEPHERDING EVERYBODY AND GIVING
A GREAT INFORMATION FLOW, BUT
ULTIMATELY THEY ARE MAYBE
TRAINED FOR IT BUT HAVE HAD NO
EXPERIENCE WITH THIS.
ONE HOMICIDE IN THIS TOWN IN TEN
YEARS, WHAT IS IT LIKE FOR
POLICE IN A SITUATION LIKE THAT
WHO DON'T DEAL WITH THESE
SITUATIONS ON A REGULAR BASIS?
WHEN THEY GET THE CALLS, THE 911
DISPATCH CALLS THAT TELLS THEM
THERE'S A SHOOTING IN A SCHOOL
ON LOCKDOWN AND THEY ARE HEARING
GUNFIRE?
>> IT APPEARS IN THIS CASE THE
POLICE ACTION WAS EXCEPTIONALLY
WELL COORDINATED AND WELL
EXECUTED.
THEY WENT TO THE SCENE AND
DIDN'T KNOW IF THEY HAD MORE
SHOOTERS.
HAY HAD TO NOT ONLY SECURE THE
PREMESIS BUT GO THROUGHOUT THE
COMMUNITY.
KIDS RAN OUT OF THE SCHOOL WITH
NO TELLING WHERE THEY RAN TO.
THE POSSIBILITY OF ADDITIONAL
SHOOTERS THAT MAY HAVE RUN INTO
THE WOODED AREA SURROUNDING THE
SCHOOL, SO THE POLICE HAD AN
OVERWHELMING TASK FROM THE FIRST
MINUTE OF THIS INCIDENT TO
REALLY EVEN CONTINUE WITH NOW.
SO IN THIS CASE THEY DEFERRED TO
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE WHO
TOOK COMMAND OF THE SITUATION
AND ALL THE OTHER AGENCIES THAT
ARE WORKING HERE ARE UNDER THAT
COMMAND AND PROVIDING ASSISTANCE
TO THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE.
AND THAT INCLUDES THE FEDERAL
AGENCIES, THE FBI, ATF, ANY
OTHER AGENCIES FROM THROUGHOUT
THE STATE OR OTHER STATE THAT IS
CAME TO PROVIDE ASSISTANCE TO
THEM.
NO ONE TOWN COULD HANDLE THE
SITUATION.
THE AMOUNT OF INVESTIGATIVE WORK
IN THIS SITUATION IS JUST
INCREDIBLE.
AND I KNOW FROM EXPERIENCE THAT
YOU CAN'T DO IT BY YOURSELF.
NO ONE AGENCY COULD DO IT.
THEY NEED EVERYBODY'S HELP IN
THIS SITUATION.
>> Reporter: WE ARE EXPECTING TO
HEAR FROM THE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE MOMENTARILY.
THAT PRESS CONFERENCE WAS
SLALTED TO START A HALF HOUR
AGO.
THEY ARE RUNNING LATE.
THEY ARE HERE TRYING TO GATHER
AS MUCH INFORMATION AS THEY
POSSIBLY CAN.
THEY ARE DOING A GREAT JOB OF
TRYING TO KEEP THE COUNTRY AND
THE WORLD INFORMED AS TO WHAT
THEY KNOW.
JOHN, WE'LL TALK TO JOHN BERMAN
IN A MOMENT.
TOM FUENTES, THANK YOU FOR THAT.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH THAT
PRESS CONFERENCE AND WITH MORE
INFORMATION.
YOU'RE WATCHING CNN.
THOSE ARE GOOD THINGS.
UPSTAIRS, THEY WILL SEE FANTASY.
NOT FANTASY... LOGISTICS.
UPS CAME IN, ANALYZED OUR SUPPLY
CHAIN, INVENTORY SYSTEMS...
UPS?
UPS.
NOT FANTASY?
WHO WOULD HAVE THOUGHT?
I DID.
WE DID, BOB. WE DID.
GOT IT.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
♪
>>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
>> THAT WAS A VISIBLY SHAKEN
PRESIDENT OBAMA.
A VISION OF PRESIDENT OBAMA NONE
OF US HAD SCENE.
A VISION OF A PRESIDENT MANY OF
US HAD NEVER SEEN.
THAT WAS JUST HOURS AFTER
YESTERD
YESTERDAY'S EASTER TERRIBLE
SHOOTING.
WE ARE EXPECTING A NEWS
CONFERENCE ANY MINUTE FROM THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE AND
WILL BRING THAT TO YOU THE
SECOND IT HAPPENS.
WE ARE TOLD THEY MAY RELEASE
SOME OF THE NAMES OF THE
VICTIMS, INCLUDING THE NAME OF
THE CHILDREN.
SOME 20 KIDS AGES 5 TO 10 KILLED
IN THIS AWFUL, AWFUL EVENT.
I WANT TO GO TO WASHINGTON NOW
TO BRING IN CNN'S WHITE HOUSE
CORRESPONDENT BRIANNA KIELER.
THE PRESIDENT DIDN'T JUST SPEAK
YESTERDAY, HE DEDICATED HIS
WEEKLY ADDRESS TO THE SHOOTING
VICTIMS.
>> Reporter: THAT'S RIGHT.
NO DOUBT HIS ADDRESS WOULD HAVE
BEEN ABOUT THE LOOMING TAX CUTS
HE'S WORKING WITH HOUSE
REPUBLICANS ON.
THAT WAS OCCUPYING WASHINGTON,
TAKING UP ALL THE OXYGEN HERE
UNTIL THIS SHOOTING HAPPENED.
OF COURSE, IT IS NOT SURPRISING,
THIS IS COMPLETELY SHIFTING THE
CONVERSATION IN WASHINGTON.
PRESIDENT OBAMA TALKING ABOUT
THE CONNECTICUT SHOOTING IN HIS
WEEKLY ADDRESS, TOUCHING AGAIN
ON A PERSONAL NOTE.
HERE'S PART OF IT.
>> THIS WEEKEND MICHELLE AND I
ARE DOING WHAT EVERY PARENT IS
DOING, HOLDING OUR CHILDREN AS
CLOSE AS WE CAN AND REMINDING
THEM HOW MUCH WE LOVE THEM.
THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CAN'T DO THAT
TODAY AND THEY NEED ALL OF US
RIGHT NOW.
BECAUSE WHILE NOTHING CAN TAKE
THE PLACE OF A LOST CHILD OR
LOVED ONE, ALL OF US CAN EXTEND
THE HAND TO THOSE IN NEED TO
REMIND THEM THAT WE ARE THERE
FOR THEM.
THAT WE ARE PRAYING FOR THEM.
AND THAT THE LOVE THEY FELT FOR
THOSE THEY LOST ENDURES NOT JUST
IN THEIR OWN MEMORIES BUT ALSO
IN THEIR COMMUNITIES AND IN
THEIR COUNTRY.
>> Reporter: NOW PRESIDENT OBAMA
HAD ALSO SAID IN HIS WEEKLY
ADDRESS AS A NATION WE HAVE
ENDURED FAR TOO MANY OF THESE
TRAGEDIES IN THE LAST FEW YEARS.
JOHN, THAT'S SOMETHING THAT
REALLY STRIKES ME WHEN I THINK
OF THE TRAGEDIES THAT PRESIDENT
OBAMA PERSONALLY HAS HAD TO TALK
ABOUT, TRY TO STRIKE THIS TONE
OF UNITY ON, REMEMBER
CONGRESSWOMAN GABBY GIFFORDS.
HE WENT TO ARIZONA.
AURORA, COLORADO, HE WENT TO
COLORADO TO TRY TO DELIVER A
MESSAGE OF UNITY.
AND ALSO THAT TEMPLE SHOOTING IN
WISCONSIN.
SO HE'S DEALT WITH A NUMBER OF
THESE HORRIBLE INSTANCES.
AND I THINK KIND OF WHEN YOU
LOOK BACK IN THE LAST FEW YEARS,
IT JUST STRIKES YOU HOW MANY AND
HOW WE HAVE SEEN SO MANY OF
THEM.
LY TELL YOU PRESIDENT OBAMA IS
RECEIVING REGULAR UPDATES FROM
HIS HOMELAND SECURITY TEAM AND
HIS MAIN HOMELAND SECURITY
ADVISER.
HE'S ALSO IN TOUCH, OF COURSE,
WITH STATE OFFICIALS IN
CONNECTICUT GETTING THE VERY
SLATEST ON WHAT'S HAPPENING
THERE, JOHN.
>> Reporter: BRIANNA, ONE OF THE
THINGS HE MENTIONED IN HIS
REMARKS YESTERDAY WAS THAT HE
HAD SO MANY OF THE TRAGIC EVENTS
LIKE YOU SAID AND IT WAS TIME TO
TAKE SOME TYPE OF MEANINGFUL
ACTION.
THE WORDS WERE MEANINGFUL.
AS THE WHITE HOUSE OFFICIALS
EXPLAIN EXACTLY WHAT HE MEANT BY
THAT?
>> Reporter: THEY HAVEN'T.
THIS WAS SOMETHING JAY CARNEY
WAS PRESSED ON IN THE BRIEFING
YESTERDAY WAS WHAT ABOUT GUN
LEGISLATION?
THIS IS SOMETHING THAT THE
PRESIDENT HAS TALKED ABOUT IN
LOOSE TERMS BUT HAS NOT PROPOSED
SPECIFICS ON.
PART OF THAT IS WHEN YOU LOOK AT
CONGRESS, EVEN DEMOCRATS, THERE
ISN'T A WILL TO PASS ANY SORT OF
GUN CONTROL LEGISLATION.
IT IS AN ISSUE REALLY FALLING
OFF THE LIST OF PRIORITIES OF
THINGS TO DO.
THIS WAS THE CASE IN HIS LAST
TERM.
THIS IS THE EXPECTATION IN THE
NEXT TERM.
AND IT'S UNCLEAR IF THIS
SHOOTING WILL REALLY FURTHER
THAT.
WE HAVE SEEN AS I MENTIONED
ALMOST THIS SORT OF LITANY OF
THESE FORABLE TRAGEDIES, NONE OF
WHICH HAVE PUSHED FORWARD ANY
SORT OF GUN LEGISLATION IN
RESPONSE TO THEM.
SO THERE WILL BE A LOT OF
QUESTIONS ABOUT HOW THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT RESPONDS TO THIS,
JOHN, BUT AT THIS POINT IT IS
UNCLEAR AND THERE REALLY AREN'T
ANY SPECIFICS THERE ABOUT
WHETHER SOMETHING NEW WOULD BE
PROPOSED, MAY CONTINUING TO PUSH
EXISTING LEGISLATION.
WE JUST DON'T KNOW.
>> Reporter: YEAH, HE USED THE
WORDS MEANINGFUL ACTION
YESTERDAY.
MAYOR MICHAEL BLOOMBERG A FIERCE
GUN CONTROLLED A ADVOVATE ALSO
MENTIONED IT IS TIME FOR ACTION.
BEFORE I LET YOU GO, YOU
MENTIONED THE NEGOTIATIONS FOR
THE FISCAL CLIFF.
WERE THE NEGOTIATIONS THERE?
DOES HE HAVE TO JUGGLE THIS NOW
OR HOW WILL HE JUGGLE THIS?
IS THERE A SENSE OF WHAT WILL
HAPPEN TO THOSE DISCUSSIONS THE
NEXT FEW DAYS?
>> Reporter: IT IS UNCLEAR AT
THIS POINT.
I WILL TELL YOU, SPEAKING TO
AIDES CLOSE TO PRESIDENT OBAMA
YESTERDAY, THIS SHOOTING HAS
VERY MUCH OCCUPIED HIS TIME.
THAT'S NOT REALLY A SURPRISE,
THAT'S WHAT YOU WOULD EXPECT.
HE'S VERY MUCH TURNED HIS
ATTENTION TO THIS.
THAT COULD CHANGE IN THE NEXT
COUPLE OF DAYS AND ALSO IT IS
NOT JUST PRESIDENT OBAMA
INVOLVED WITH THE SPEAKER, WITH
SPEAKER BOEHNER IN THE
DISCUSSIONS.
THERE ARE THINGS GOING ON AT THE
STAFF LEVEL.
THOSE DISCUSSIONS ABOUT THE
FISCAL CLIFF CAN CONTINUE BUT
CERTAINLY AT LEAST PUBLICLY
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL BE FOCUSING
ON THE SHOOTING IN CONNECTICUT.
>> Reporter: THAT'S RIGHT.
LEADING THE NATION IN GRIEVING
AND MOURNING THOSE LOST.
BRIANNA KIELER AT THE WHITE
HOUSE, THANK YOU FOR JOINING US
THIS MORNING.
GREAT TO SEE YOU.
IT IS MORNING NOW IN NEWTOWN.
AND THE TIGHTLY-KNIT CONNECTICUT
TOWN IS GRIEVING TODAY LIKE SO
MUCH OF THE NATION FOR THE 20
CHILDREN, SEVEN ADULTS LOST
THEIR LIVES SO SUDDENLY AND
HORRIBLY TO THIS GUNMAN.
NEWTOWN STUNNED RESIDENTS
GATHERED AT VIGILS LAST NIGHT
INCLUDING ONE AT ST. ROSE OF
LIMA CHURCH TO COMFORT EACH
OTHER.
THEY WILL HAVE MORE VIGILS IN
THE DAYS AND NIGHTS TO COME.
PEOPLE ARE ALREADY STREAMING
INTO THIS CHURCH TODAY TO PRAY.
WE WANT TO TAKE A LOOK NOW AT
THIS REPORT FROM OUR AFFILIATE,
WTIC.
>> SO WE NEED TO BE HERE TO PRAY
FOR THESE PEOPLE.
>> Reporter: DOORS WILL BE OPEN
FOR THOSE CLOSE TOAST THE
TRAGEDY.
>> I'M IN A MATH CLASS WITH THE
YOUNGER BROTHER OF A BOY THAT
WAS KILLED.
IT WAS 9:30 AND THIS HAPPENED
SHORTLY BEFORE 10:00.
IT WAS CRAZY.
>> Reporter: FOR ANYONE WHO
FEELS AFFECTED --
>> ANYONE IN THE TOWN IS REALLY
DEVASTATED BY THIS THING.
IT IS SUCH A SMALL TOWN AND I
FEEL LIKE THIS IS GOING TO BRING
EVERYONE TOGETHER EVEN THOUGH IT
IS SUCH A TRAGEDY.
>> Reporter: -- AND FOR ALL
THOSE WHO GRIEVE FOR LIVES LOST
TOO YOUNG.
>> LIKE THE PASTOR NOW SAID, WE
HAVE 20 NEW ANGELS IN OUR TOWN
WATCHING OVER US.
>> Reporter: WE ARE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WE ARE AWAITING A NEWS
CONFERENCE FROM CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE TO UPDATE US ON THE
INVESTIGATION TO UPDATE US ON
MAYBE TO EXPECT SOME NAMES OF
THE VICTIMS HERE IN NEWTOWN.
THAT NEWS CONFERENCE HAS NOT
STARTED BUT WE'LL BRING IT TO
YOU THE MINUTE, THE MINUTE, THE
SECOND IT BEGINS.
IN THE MEANTIME, LET'S GO OVER
TO ALI VELSHI IN NEWTOWN.
>> Reporter: JOHN, IT PROMISES
TO START, IT WAS SUPPOSED TO
START A HALF HOUR AGO.
WE HAVE SEEN THE STATE POLICE
OFFICIALS WHO ARE HERE WHO
SHOULD BE LEADING THIS NEWS
CONFERENCE.
AS YOU HAVE POINTED OUT, THE
POLICE OFFICIALS, THE
AUTHORITIES HERE HAVE BEEN VERY,
VERY GOOD AT GIVING OUT
INFORMATION.
THEY ARE ALSO INTERESTED IN
GIVING OUT ACCURATE INFORMATION.
MANY TIMES WE FIND IN EVENTS
LIKE THIS THERE'S A PUSH TO GET
INFORMATION OUT.
LOOK, IT'S BEEN 23 HOURS SINCE
THIS HAPPENED AND ALREADY THERE
HAVE BEEN SEVERAL STORIES THAT
WERE THOUGHT TO BE TRUE THAT
HAVE NOT TURNED OUT TO BE TRUE.
I WANT TO BRING IN MIKE BROOKS
IN ATLANTA.
HLN'S LAW ENFORCEMENT ANALYST.
MIKE, WE HAVE COVERED A NUMBER
OF THESE SORTS OF THINGS IN THE
PAST, PROBABLY NONE AS TRAGIC AS
THIS.
LET'S TALK ABOUT THE SHOOTER,
ADAM LANZA, WHO IS ALLEGED TO
HAVE TAKEN HIS MOTHER'S LIFE AT
THEIR HOME TWO-AND-A-HALF MILES
FROM HERE AND THEN GOING TO THE
SCHOOL.
HE HAD TWO GUNS ON THEM AND ONE
SEMIAUTOMATIC BUSHMASTER IN THE
CAR APPARENTLY LICENSED TO HIS
MOTHER, BUT APPARENTLY HE HAD
ACCESS TO AT LEAST FIVE GUNS
ACCORDING TO A LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIAL WITH DIRECT KNOWLEDGE
OF THE INVESTIGATION.
HE'S ASKED FOR ANONYMITY BECAUSE
OF THE ONGOING INVESTIGATION.
WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF THIS?
HE WAS FOUND DEAD IN THE
CLASSROOM WITH TWO FIREARMS, A
GLR
GLOCK AND A SIG SAUER.
THEY ARE GUNS POPULAR AMONG LAW
ENFORCEMENT.
>> THEY ARE.
I HAD A SIG SAUER AS MY SERVICE
WEAPON.
AND I ALSO HAD A GLOCK.
THEY ARE HIGH-QUALITY
SEMIAUTOMATIC HANDGUNS.
AGAIN, THEY BELONGED TO HIS
MOTHER.
BUT HE HAD APPARENTLY DIRECT
ACCESS TO THESE GUNS.
SO, AND HE APPARENTLY, MOST
LIKELY, DID NOT HAVE A
BACKGROUND CHECK, BUT WE DON'T
KNOW WHAT TRANSPIRED INSIDE THAT
HOUSE BEFORE HE CAME TO THAT
SCHOOL AND WENT ON A RAMPAGE.
BUT WE ARE LOOKING AT THE
PICTURES OF THESE WEAPONS RIGHT
NOW.
WE SAW THE GLOCK ON THE UPPER
LEFT.
WE SAW THE SIG SAUER.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT CALIBER THE
GUNS WERE.
THESE ARE EXAMPLES.
WE DON'T KNOW IFS AFTER A .9
MILLIMETER AND WE DON'T KNOW
WHAT KIND OF MODEL OF A
BUSHMASTER IT IS.
IT IS AN AR-15 WEAPON THAT FIRES
A CARTRIDGE BASICALLY LIKE THE
MILITARY USES.
WHY WOULD ANYONE HAVE THIS GUN?
THERE ARE A LOT OF PEOPLE WHO DO
OWN WEAPONS LIKE THIS FOR TARGET
SHOOTING.
SOME PEOPLE, EVEN SOME HUNT WITH
THEM.
BUT THERE ARE A LOT OF THEM OUT
THERE AND PEOPLE DO USE THEM FOR
TARGET PRACTICE.
AND ALSO SELF-DEFENSE.
>> Reporter: UNDER WHAT
CIRCUMSTANCES WOULD YOU BE USING
A BUSHMASTER FOR SELF-DEFENSE?
>> WELL, A LOT OF PEOPLE FEEL
THEY NEED ONE IN THEIR HOME FOR
WHATEVER REASON.
AND IT IS, YOU CAN USE ANY
WEAPON FOR SELF-DEFENSE.
BUT AGAIN, THAT STIRS A LOT OF
CONTROVERSY.
AND A LOT OF DISCUSSION ABOUT
GUN LAWS, BUT I'M SURE WE'LL BE
TALKING ABOUT THAT AS WE MOVE
FORWARD FROM THIS EVENT.
>> Reporter: MIKE, CONNECTICUT
IS ONE OF THOSE STATES THAT DOES
HAVE SOME STRICT GUN LAWS.
A GUN REGISTRY TO MEET CERTAIN
REQUIREMENTS HERE.
YOU HAVE TO TAKE A COURSE, IN
FACT, IN GUN OPERATION.
TALK TO ME ABOUT THOSE PISTOLS.
WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF THOSE
PISTOLS?
THE PICTURES WE SHOWED, WHICH
ARE NOT THE GUNS USED, HAVE A
STANDARD MAGAZINE OF 15 BULLETS?
15 ROUNDS?
>> YEAH, MAGAZINES IN THOSE
RANGE FROM 15 TO 19.
THEY DO MAKE EXTENDED MAGAZINES
FOR EACH OF THE WEAPONS THAT CAN
HOLD POSSIBLY UP TO 30 ROUNDS,
DEPENDING IF IT IS A SINGLE OR
DOUBLE STACK MAGAZINE.
BUT WE DON'T KNOW, WE HAVE NOT
HEARD HOW MANY MAGAZINES HE HAD
INSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
BUT AS TOM FUENTES POINTED OUT
EARLIER, IF HE HAD EXTRA
MAGAZINES AND CAME IN AND HAD TO
RELOAD, HE PROBABLY WAS --
NOBODY WAS CHALLENGING HIM
BECAUSE THEY WERE ALL LITTLE
CHILDREN WITH SOME OF THE ADULT
TEACHERS, ALI.
SO HE WOULD JUST WALK AROUND
WITH IMPUNITY SHOOTING AT THE
LITTLE CHILDREN.
>> Reporter: RIGHT.
THE TEACHERS WERE OCCUPIED,
THOSE THAT WE HAVE BEEN ABLE TO
FIND OUT WERE OCCUPIED AND TRIED
TO PROTECT THE KIDS, HIDE THEM
AND COVER THEM SO THEY WEREN'T
IN A POSITION TO CONFRONT HIM.
ALL RIGHT, MIKE, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
WE'LL CHECK IN WITH YOU LATER,
MIKE BROOKS, FORMER FBI MEMBER.
SO MANY QUESTIONS AND SO FEW
ANSWERS NOW.
TEACHERS AND EMERGENCY
RESPONDERS TALKING ABOUT HOW TO
KEEP THEIR SCHOOLS SAFE.
AND MANY PARENTS ARE CONSOLING
THEIR CHILDREN.
>> MY KIDS ARE ALREADY ASKING
WHEN IS THIS GOING TO HAPPEN
AGAIN.
IT WAS ONLY A WEEK AGO THAT WE
WERE TALKING ABOUT THIS TYPE OF
SITUATION AND I SAID, THE
CHANCES OF IT HAPPENING ARE ONE
IN A ZILLION AT SANDY HOOK.
AND I WAS WRONG ABOUT THAT.
♪
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
PROGRESSIVE DIRECT AND OTHER
CAR INSURANCE COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
CALL OR CLICK TODAY.
>>> 8:45 EASTERN TIME.
WELCOME BACK, EVERYONE.
I'M ALI VELSHI.
YOU ARE WATCHING OUR SPECIAL
COVERAGE OF THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
WE ARE LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WE ARE ALSO GETTING SOME INSIGHT
INTO HOW ALL OF THIS UNFOLDED.
HERE'S A SMALL PART OF THE RADIO
TRANSMISSION BETWEEN POLICE WHEN
THEY GOT WORD OF THE SHOOTING.
>> 6-7 SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
THE CALLER INDICATES THERE'S A
SHOOTING INSIDE THE BUILDING.
>> THE FRONT GLASS HAS BEEN
BROKEN.
THEY ARE UNSURE WHY.
ALL UNITS, THE INDIVIDUAL THAT I
HAVE ON THE PHONE IS CONTINUING
TO HEAR WHAT HE BELIEVES TO BE
GUNFIRE.
UNIT RESPONDING TO SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL AT THIS TIME.
THE SHOOTING APPEARS TO HAVE
STOPPED.
THE SCHOOL IS IN LOCKDOWN.
>> Reporter: JOHN BERMAN IS ALSO
WITH ME IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE HAVE OUR CNN TEAM SPREAD
ACROSS THE CITY.
JOHN, YOU ARE AT THE SITE OF ONE
OF SEVERAL VIGILS HELD LAST
NIGHT.
AND THIS TOWN WAKES UP THIS
MORNING TO A PRESS CONFERENCE WE
ARE JUST WAITING TO BEGIN TO GET
THAT STARTED WHERE THEY ARE
GOING TO, WE EXPECT, HEAR THE
NAMES OF THOSE 20 CHILDREN, SIX
ADULTS.
WE KNOW TWO OF THE ADULTS'
NAMES.
A PRINCIPAL AND THE PSYCHOLOGIST
FROM THE SCHOOL, BUT WE'LL HEAR
A LOT MORE NAMES.
AND IT WILL SEND THIS UP TO
REELING ALL OVER AGAIN, JOHN.
>> Reporter: ALI, THIS IS THE
ST. ROSE OF LIMA CHURCH BEHIND
ME WHERE LAST NIGHT THERE WAS A
VIGIL.
A THOUSAND PEOPLE WERE HERE
INSIDE AND OUTSIDE THIS CHURCH
TO MOURN TOGETHER AND GRIEVE
TOGETHER.
THIS TOWN REALLY IS GOING
THROUGH THIS AS ONE TIGHT-KNIT
COMMUNITY.
I HEARD BELLS A SHORT WHILE AGO
AND DIDN'T KNOW WHY OR WHERE
THEY WERE RINGING, BUT IT DID
GIVE THE SENSE OF TOGETHERNESS
THAT IS REALLY PERMEATING INSIDE
THIS COMMUNITY.
THE CHURCH HERE IS FILLING UP
AGAIN THIS MORNING WITH PARENTS,
FAMILIES, PEOPLE HERE TO SHARE
IN THIS MOMENT.
THERE ARE TWO BULLETIN BOARDS
SET UP FOR PEOPLE TO START
POSTING MESSAGES.
MESSAGES OF HOPE AND MESSAGES OF
MOURNING.
I SPOKE TO A FATHER A SHORT
WHILE AGO, ALI, OF A CHILD, AN
8-YEAR-OLD GIRL, A THIRD GRADER,
A SURVIVOR FROM THIS.
AND HE, LIKE SO MANY PARENTS, IS
STRUGGLING TO TALK TO HIS KIDS
THIS WEEKEND.
THEY WANT TO KNOW HOW DO YOU
COMMUNICATE TO THEM WHAT
HAPPENED AND WHAT SHOULD HAPPEN?
HE TOLD ME THAT HIS KIDS, THIS
8-YEAR-OLD GIRL AND 10-YEAR-OLD
SON DON'T WANT TO GO BACK TO
SCHOOL ON MONDAY, WHICH IS
UNDERSTANDABLE.
THERE HAS TO BE SO MANY EMOTIONS
GOING THROUGH THEIR HEADS RIGHT
NOW.
AND FROM THE YOUNG CHILDREN WHO
WERE AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL TO THEIR FRIGHTENED
PARENTS, WE HAVE MORE ON THOSE
WHO WERE WITNESS TO FRIDAY'S
TRAGIC EVENTS.
>> Reporter: THE ACCOUNT OF A
YOUNG BOY SET TO BE DELIVERING
AN ATTENDANCE REPORT TO THE
OFFICE AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL WHEN THE SHOOTINGS TOOK
PLACE IS SURREAL.
>> I SAW SOME OF THE BULLETS
GOING PAST THE HALL THAT I WAS
RIGHT NEXT TO.
AND THEN A TEACHER PULLED ME
INTO HER CLASSROOM.
>> Reporter: HE SAID HE HEARD A
SOUND LIKE SOMEONE KICKING A
DOOR.
HIS MOTHER CLINGING TO HIM HAD
WORDS OF THANKS.
>> I'M JUST SO GRATEFUL TO THE
TEACHER WHO SAVED HIM.
>> Reporter: YOU THINK THE
TEACHER SAVED HIS LIFE?
>> SHE DEFINITELY DID.
HE HAD BULLETS GOING BY HIM AND
SHE GRABBED HIM AND ANOTHER
CHILD AND PULLED THEM INTO A
CLASSROOM.
>> Reporter: BRENDON MURRAY, A
FOURTH GRADER, DESCRIBED THE
CHAOS.
>> I WAS IN THE GYM AT THE TIME,
AND SO THE TEACHER, WE HEARD
LOTS OF BANGS, AND WE THOUGHT
THAT IT WAS THE CUSTODIAN
KNOCKING STUFF DOWN.
THEN WE HEARD SCREAMING.
AND SO WE -- SO WE -- WE WENT ON
TO, LIKE WE WENT TO THE WALL AND
WE SAT DOWN.
AND THEN A POLICE CAME IN, IT'S
LIKE, IS HE IN HERE?
THEN HE RAN OUT.
THEN OUR TEACHER, THEN SOMEBODY
YELLED, GET TO A SAFE PLACE.
SO WE WENT INTO A CLOSET IN THE
GYM AND SAT THERE FOR A LITTLE
WHILE.
AND THEN THE POLICE WERE
KNOCKING ON THE DOOR AND THEY
ARE LIKE, WE ARE EVACUATING
PEOPLE, WE ARE EVACUATING
PEOPLE.
>> Reporter: CNN IS ONLY AIRING
SOUND OF CHILDREN WHOSE PARENTS
GAVE PERMISSION AS ONE WOMAN
WALKED AWAY FROM THE SCHOOL SHE
WAS HEARD CRYING, "WHY?
WHY?"
A POLICEMAN SAID IT WAS THE
WORST THING HE'S SEEN IN HIS
CAREER.
A NURSE FROM NEARBY DANBURY
HOSPITAL DESCRIBED THE SCENE
THERE AS PARENTS WAITED FOR WORD
ON THEIR CHILDREN.
>> ALL THESE PARENTS WERE
WAITING FOR THEIR CHILDREN TO
COME OUT.
THEY THOUGHT THAT THEY WERE, YOU
KNOW, STILL ALIVE.
THERE WAS 20 PARENTS THAT WERE
JUST TOLD THAT THEIR CHILDREN
ARE DEAD.
IT WAS AWFUL.
>> Reporter: THE FATHER OF A
YOUNG GIRL WHO SURVIVED WAS JUST
TRYING TO PROCESS IT ALL.
>> IT WAS SHOCKING.
I GOT THE CALL AT WORK THIS
MORNING AND I CAN'T BELIEVE A
SMALL TOWN LIKE THIS WOULD EVER
HAVE ANYTHING LIKE THIS HAPPEN.
AND TO BE IN AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, THAT'S UNHEARD OF.
>> Reporter: BY LATE FRIDAY
AFTERNOON AND INTO THE EVENING,
EVACUATED CHILDREN WERE BEING
CARED FOR AND REUNITING WITH
THEIR PARENTS AT A NEARBY
FIREHOUSE.
BRIAN TODD, CNN, WASHINGTON.
>> Reporter: WE ARE STILL
WAITING ON THE NEWS CONFERENCE
HERE BY CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
WHERE AUTHORITIES ARE EXPECTED
TO RELEASE THE NAMES OF THE 20
CHILDREN AND 6 ADULTS GUNNED
DOWN INSIDE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AND WE ARE GOING TO LEARN MORE
PERHAPS ABOUT THE GUNMAN.
I WANT TO CHECK WITH NICK
VALENCIA AT THE CNN CENTER.
WE HAVE MORE INFORMATION RIGHT
NOW, I BELIEVE, ABOUT THE FATHER
OF THE GUNMAN.
WHAT INFORMATION DO YOU HAVE?
>> YEAH, JOHN, OUR NEWS DESK
TEAM HAS BEEN WORKING TIRELESSLY
TO GET THE LATEST INFORMATION ON
THE VICTIMS.
JUST A SHORT WHILE AGO WE WERE
ABLE TO CLEAR THE USAGE OF A
LINKEDN PROFILE FOR THE FATHER
OF THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER, ADAM
LANZA.
THE FATHER HERE, IF WE CAN BRING
THAT PICTURE UP, PETER LANZA.
THIS IS THE PHOTO OF THE FATHER,
OF THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER.
20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER ADAM LANZA.
THIS PICTURE JUST INTO CNN, THIS
IS HIS FATHER, PETER LANZA.
CNN HAS MADE EFFORTS TO TRY TO
REACH OUT TO HIM, I HAVE TRYING
TO GET HIM ON THE PHONE, BUT WE
HAVE BEEN UNSUCCESSFUL THIS
MORNING.
WE ARE MAKING EFFORTS TO GET IN
TOUCH WITH HIM.
THIS PHOTO JUST CAME INTO CNN.
THIS IS THE PHOTO OF THE FATHER
OF THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER ADAM
LANZA.
THIS PICTURED ON THE SCREEN IS
PETER LANZA.
CNN TRIED TO REACH OUT TO PETER
LANZA AND HAS BEEN UNSUCCESSFUL.
WE ARE STILL STANDING BY FOR
WHAT WAS AN 8:00 A.M. PRESS
CONFERENCE RUNNING AN HOUR LATE
HERE, BUT LOCAL POLICE ARE
EXPECTED TO RELEASE THE NAMES OF
MORE VICTIMS.
SO FAR WE HAVE BEEN ABLE TO
CONFIRM THE NAMES OF TWO ADULTS,
TWO OF THE SIX ADULTS SHOT
YESTERDAY IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THAT WAS AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
JOHN?
>> Reporter: ALL RIGHT, NICK
VALENCIA THERE IN ATLANTA, THANK
YOU FOR BRINGING US THAT.
AS NICK SAID, WE ARE AWAITING A
NEWS CONFERENCE HERE.
MOMENTS AWAY, WE THINK, FROM
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE WHERE
THEY ARE EXPECTED TO RELEASE THE
NAMES OF THE VICTIMS OF THOSE
KILLED INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS DECEMBER, REMEMBER --
♪
YOU CAN STAY IN
AND LIKE SOMETHING...
♪
[ car alarm deactivates ]
...OR YOU CAN GET OUT THERE
WITH YOUR FAMILY
AND ACTUALLY LIKE SOMETHING.
♪
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON,
OFFERING SOME OF OUR BEST
VALUES OF THE YEAR.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
THERE'S A HEALTH COMPANY THAT
CAN HELP YOU STAY THAT WAY.
WHAT'S HEALTHIER THAN THAT?
WELL, IF ITMR. MARGIN?MARGIN.
DON'T BE MODEST, BOB.
YOU FOUND A BETTER WAY
TO PACK A BOWLING BALL.
THAT WAS UPS.
AND WHO CALLED UPS?
YOU DID, BOB.
I JUST ASKED A QUESTION.
IT TAKES A LONG TIME
TO PACK A BOWLING BALL.
THE LAST GUY PITCHED
MORE BALL PACKERS.
BUT YOU... YOU CONSULTED UPS.
YOU FOUND A BETTER WAY.
THAT'S LOGISTICS.
THAT'S MARGIN.
FIND OUT WHAT ELSE UPS KNOWS.
I'LL DO THAT.
YOU'RE ON A ROLL.
THAT'S FUNNY.
I WASN'T BEING FUNNY, BOB.
I KNOW.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYONE.
JOHN BERMAN HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WHERE WE ARE AWAITING A NEWS
CONFERENCE FROM THE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE WHO HAVE BEEN SO
CONSCIENTIOUS IN UPDATING US ON
THE SITUATION HERE.
THE INVESTIGATION, THEY WERE
DOING IT EVERY HOUR YESTERDAY
AFTERNOON AND INTO THE EVENING.
AND THEY SCHEDULED A NEWS
CONFERENCE FOR THIS MORNING AS
WELL.
IT WAS SUPPOSED TO BEGIN ONE
HOUR AGO.
IT'S OBVIOUSLY BEEN DELAYED.
WE HAVE SEEN OFFICIALS THERE
MILLING ABOUT SO HOPEFULLY IT
WILL GET GOING SOON.
THEY HAVE BEEN GOOD ABOUT GIVING
US ACCURATE INFORMATION.
PERHAPS THEY ARE GETTING THE
LAST BIT OF INFORMATION TOGETHER
NOW.
WE'LL BRING YOU THE NEWS
CONFERENCE THE MINUTE IT BEGINS.
IN THE MEANTIME, CNN LEGAL
CONTRIBUTOR PAUL KALLEN IS LIVE
FROM NEW YORK, A CRIMINAL
DEFENSE ATTORNEY, A FORMER NEW
YORK CITY HOMICIDE PROSECUTOR.
PAUL, RIGHT NOW THIS MORNING,
OVERNIGHT, EVERYONE TALKING
ABOUT GUN CONTROL.
BUT IF THE SUSPECT GOT THESE
GUNS FROM HIS MOTHER WHO WE
BELIEVE HE DID, AND THEY WERE
LEGALLY REGISTERED, WOULD
STRONGER GUN CONTROL LAWS HAVE
MADE ANY DIFFERENCE?
>> I DON'T THINK STRONGER GUN
CONTROL LAWS WOULD MAKE A
DIFFERENCE IN THIS CASE BASED ON
WHAT WE KNOW.
CONNECTICUT HAS RELATIVELY TOUGH
GUN LAWS.
YOU NEED A PERMIT TO BUY A
HANDGUN AND IN ORDER TO GET THE
HANDGUN YOU HAVE TO DO A
BACKGROUND CHECK, YOU NEED A
FINGERPRINT AND THE WOMAN KEPT
THE GUNS IN THE HOUSE.
IT IS HARD TO GET A CARRY PERMIT
AND THERE'S NO EVIDENCE OF THE
CARRY PERMIT.
AND THE MILITARY-STYLE WEAPON,
FRANKLY, IN MOST STATES WOULD BE
LEGAL BECAUSE IT IS CONSIDERED
TO BE A RIFLE OR SHOTGUN.
IT IS NOT AN AUTOMATIC WEAPON.
PEOPLE CALL THOSE AUTOMATIC
WEAPONS BUT AN AUTOMATIC WEAPON
WHEN YOU PULL THE TRIGGER YOU
GET MACHINE FIRING OF THE
BULLETS AS OPPOSED TO ONE BULLET
WERE PULL, WHICH MAKES IT A
SEMIAUTOMATIC AND LEGAL.
SO I THINK IN THE END UNLESS YOU
BANNED ALL GUNS COMPLETELY, YOU
COULDN'T HAVE ANY EFFECT ON A
SITUATION LIKE THIS.
AND IN MOST STATES IN
CONNECTICUT, HUNTING WEAPONS ARE
PERMITTED.
SO I DON'T KNOW THAT THIS WILL
AFFECT THE GUN CONTROL
LEGISLATION THAT'S OUT THERE, AT
LEAST IN CONNECTICUT.
>> Reporter: ALL RIGHT.
PAUL KARREN, PLEASE STANDBY FOR
US FOR A SECOND.
IN THE MEANTIME, I WANT TO GO TO
MY FRIEND SOLEDAD O'BRIEN HERE
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE ARE AWAITING A NEWS
CONFERENCE HERE FROM OFFICIALS
TO UPDATE US ON THE SITUATION
AND THE INVESTIGATION.
GOOD MORNING, SOLEDAD.
>> Reporter: JOHN, GOOD MORNING
TO YOU.
GOOD MORNING, EVERYBODY.
I'M SOLEDAD O'BRIEN.
AND IT IS JUST AFTER 9:00 IN THE
MORNING HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
YOU'RE WATCHING OUR SPECIAL
CONTINUING COVERAGE OF THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTING.
I WANT TO WELCOME OUR AUDIENCE
AROUND THE COUNTRY AND THOSE
VIEWERS WHO ARE NOW TURNING TO
US, JOINING US FROM AROUND THE
WORLD.
LOTS TO TALK ABOUT THIS MORNING
AS WE UPDATE YOU ON THE VERY
LATEST, FIRST AND FOREMOST, AS
WE WAIT FOR THE PRESS CONFERENCE
TO GET UNDERWAY.
WE HAVE BEEN TOLD THE PRESS
CONFERENCE WOULD MOST LIKELY
START AT 8:00 THIS MORNING.
SO WE ARE AN HOUR AFTER THAT
HOUR HERE, BUT THE OFFICIALS
HAVE BEEN VERY GOOD ABOUT
CONSISTENTLY AND CONTINUOUSLY
CALLING THE PRESS CONFERENCES.
SO WE ARE WAITING FOR THEM TO
COME BACK AGAIN AND ADDRESS, I
WOULD SAY, ROUGHLY 100 REPORTERS
AND CAMERAS WHO HAVE GATHERED
HERE JUST ABOUT A HALF MILE OR
SO FROM THE SCHOOL.
LET ME TELL YOU WHERE I AM RIGHT
NOW.
OVER MY SHOULDER, OVER THIS
LITTLE HILL RIGHT THERE, THAT'S
EXACTLY WHERE IF YOU WOULD CUT
THROUGH THE WOODS, THAT'S THE
LOCATION OF YESTERDAY EASTERABLE
TRAGEDY.
THE HORRIFIC MASS SHOOTING
HAPPENED HERE.
AND HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, EVERYONE IS
SEARCHING FOR ANSWERS.
A QUESTION WE MAY NOT KNOW IS
WHY WOULD SOMEONE ATTACK AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL?
WHY ULTIMATELY WOULD THEY KILL
26 PEOPLE?
WE KNOW LAST NIGHT THE COMMUNITY
GATHERED TO PAY THEIR RESPECTS
TO TRY TO CONSOLE EACH OTHER THE
BEST THAT THEY POSSIBLY COULD,
SAY GOOD-BYE TO THE VICTIMS OF
THIS HORRIFIC TRAGEDY, 20
CHILDREN, 6 ADULTS WHO WERE
KILLED IN THE SHOOTING AT THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
I WANT TO PLAY A LITTLE BIT OF
THE RADIO TRAFFIC THAT WE WERE
ABLE TO GATHER BETWEEN THE FIRST
RESPONDERS AS THE DETAILS OF THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING STARTED TO FIRST
COME IN JUST AFTER 9:00 IN THE
MORNING.
>> MEDICS, YOU ARE REQUESTED TO
STAGE -- I WILL NEED TWO
AMBULANCES AT THIS TIME.
>> JUST RECEIVED A CALL.
WE HAVE ONE FEMALE IN ROOM ONE
WHO HAS RECEIVED A GUNSHOT WOUND
TO THE FOOT.
>> I NEED UNITS IN THE POOL,
I'VE GOT BODIES HERE.
BE ADVISED, WE DO HAVE MULTIPLE
WEAPONS INCLUDING ONE RIFLE AND
SHOTGUN.
-- REQUIRE BACKUP, AMBULANCES,
AND THEY SAID CALL FOR
EVERYTHING.
>> WHAT IS THE NUMBER OF
AMBULANCES YOU REQUIRE?
>> THEY DO NOT KNOW.
THEY ARE NOT GIVING US A NUMBER.
>> FIRE RESCUE 444, RESPOND, 12
DICKINSON DRIVE, SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL.
2-1-12, RESPOND, 12 DICKINSON
DRIVE.
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
MEDICAL EMERGENCIES.
>> I HAVE MULTIPLE AMBULANCE
PERSONNEL COMING INBOUND.
CAN WE CREATE THAT STAGING AREA
AND COMMAND AREA WITHIN THE
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL PARKING AREA?
>> Reporter: YOU CAN HEAR THE
CHAOS AND JUST HOW QUICKLY THIS
DISASTER GREW AS THEY REALIZED
THE SCOPE OF THE INJURIES AND
THE NUMBERS OF PEOPLE WHO HAD
BEEN INJURED AND KILLED.
NOW, WE ARE JUST ABOUT 90
MINUTES NORTH OF NEW YORK CITY
AND NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, IS
CONSIDERED TO BE A VERY SAFE
COMMUNITY.
THERE HAS ONLY BEEN ONE HOMICIDE
REPORTED IN THE LAST TEN YEARS
IN THIS COMMUNITY, BUT OF
COURSE, NOW UNFORTUNATELY
NEWTOWN'S NAME IS SYNONYMOUS
WITH COLUMBINE AND BLACKSBURG,
VIRGINIA, BECAUSE OF THE MASS
SHOOTING HERE.
POLICE IDENTIFIED THIS SHOOTER
AS 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA.
WE ARE ONLY NOW STARTING TO GET
A PICTURE OF WHO HE IS.
WE'LL GO TO MARY SNOW FIRST AT
LANZA'S HOME WHERE POLICE FOUND
THE BODY OF HIS MOTHER.
MARY, WHY DON'T YOU UPDATE US ON
THE VERY LATEST WE KNOW ABOUT
THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER IN THIS
CASE.
>> Reporter: SOLEDAD, IT IS
BELIEVED THAT HE LIVED HERE WITH
HIS MOTHER.
HE CAN'T SEE THE HOME BEHIND ME
WHERE THE ROAD BLOCKED OFF BY
POLICE.
THIS WAS AN ACTIVE CRIME SCENE
YESTERDAY WHERE POLICE FOUND THE
BODY OF NANCY LANZA IN THAT HOME
AND RESIDENTS WERE EVACUATED
FROM THEIR HOMES.
WE ARE TOLD INVESTIGATORS HAVE
BEEN ASKING THEM FOR ANY
INFORMATION THAT THEY HAD PIECED
TO THE WHAT THEY CAN ABOUT THIS
SUSPECT.
AND WHAT SOME OF THE THINGS WE
ARE LEARNING ABOUT HIM, ONE
NEIGHBOR DESCRIBED HIM AS
TROUBLED.
BUT IN HIS EARLIER YEARS, FORMER
CLASSMATES DESCRIBE HIM AS
SOMEONE WHO WAS VERY BRIGHT,
VERY QUIET, KEPT TO HIMSELF.
AND ACCORDING TO WHAT ONE WOMAN
WHO WAS HERE YESTERDAY, A FORMER
BUS DRIVER SAW, NOTHING THAT
REALLY STOOD OUT.
>> SOME OF THE OTHER RESIDENTS,
HE HIMSELF WAS A LITTLE FIDGETY,
A LITTLE UNEASY IF YOU WERE TO
LOOK AT HIM.
I THINK HE WAS JUST SOCIALLY NOT
INTO GOING OUT THERE AND MAKING
FRIENDS AS EVERYONE WAS REALLY
DOING IN ALMOSTRY SCHOOL AND
MIDDLE SCHOOL.
HE PREFERRED TO STAY TO HIMSELF.
>> Reporter: THAT WAS A FORMER
CLASSMATE WHO SPOKE TO CNN LAST
NIGHT.
AND SUSAN CANDIOTTI SPOKE WITH A
LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIAL WHO
SAID IN PIECES TOGETHER THIS
INFORMATION, ONE THING THEY DID
LEARN FROM A FAMILY MEMBER WHO
TOLD INVESTIGATORS, HE HAD A
FORM OF AUTISM.
SOLEDAD?
>> Reporter: WE ARE GOING TO
TALK MORE ABOUT THAT, MARY, WITH
SANJAY GUPTA.
BECAUSE AS FAR AS I KNOW, THERE
ARE NO STUDIES AT ALL THAT LINK
ANY FORM OF AUTISM WITH VIOLENT
ACTS.
SO THAT'S SOMETHING WE'LL TALK
TO OUR MEDICAL UNIT ABOUT LATER
THIS MORNING.
THANK YOU FOR THE UPDATE, MARY
SNOW, FOR US THIS MORNING.
OF COURSE, THIS IS A PARENT'S
WORST NIGHTMARE TO SEND YOUR
CHILDREN OFF TO SCHOOL AND THEN
YOU HAVE NO EXPECTATIONS THAT
JUST A FEW HOURS LATER YOU ARE
GOING TO GET A ROBOCALL MESSAGE
SAYING THE SCHOOL IS IN
LOCKDOWN.
IT HAD TO BE TERRIFYING FOR THE
PARENTS.
I WANT TO TALK TO LAURA PHELPS
AND HER HUSBAND NICK.
THEY HAVE TWO CHILDREN IN THE
SCHOOL.
A FIRST GRADER AND A THIRD
GRADER, DID YOU GET A ROBOCALL.
IS THAT HOW YOU WERE FIRST
NOTIFIED TO COME BACK TO THE
SCHOOL?
>> I DID.
THE FIRST CALL WE GOT WAS THAT
CALL.
AND IT WAS, THERE'S BEEN A
SHOOTING AND THE CHILDREN ARE IN
LOCKDOWN.
>> Reporter: WHAT DID YOU DO?
>> WE TURNED ON THE NEWS, WE
CALLED FRIENDS AND WE HADN'T
HEARD ANYTHING.
AND IT WASN'T UNTIL ON THE TV MY
SON CAME RUNNING AND SAID, IT'S
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
>> Reporter: THAT'S WHEN YOU
REALIZED IT WAS YOUR ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
>> WE WERE HOPING IT WAS NOT ONE
OF OUR SCHOOLS, IT WAS JUST A
PRECAUTION.
MAYBE IT WASN'T A REAL SHOOTING.
MAYBE JUST THINKING THIS WAS A
REAL PRECAUTION.
AND TO HEAR THAT IT WAS SANDY
HOOK WAS CERTAINLY DEVASTATING.
>> Reporter: IT HAS TO BE
HORRIBLE.
SO YOU KNOW YOU HAVE A FIRST
GRADER AND A THIRD GRADER IN
THAT SCHOOL, DID YOU RUN TO THE
SCHOOL RIGHT AWAY?
I MEAN, I WOULD HAVE RUN TO THE
SCHOOL?
>> RIGHT.
MY HUSBAND, HIS FIRST REACTION
WAS LET'S GET TO THE SCHOOL.
MY FIRST REACTION WAS LET'S LET
THE POLICE DO THE WORK, LET'S GO
TO THE CHURCH.
WE RAN TO THE CHURCH AND THEY
WERE IN LOCKDOWN.
SO WE TRIED TO GET BACK TO THE
SCHOOL AND THAT'S WHEN WE SAW
AMBULANCE AFTER AMBULANCE AND I
THOUGHT, AT THAT TIME WE HAD
HEARD POSSIBLY A TEACHER WAS
SHOT.
AND I LOOKED AT THE AMBULANCES
AND SAID TO MY HUSBAND, THIS
ISN'T ONE PERSON.
>> Reporter: TOO MANY
AMBULANCES.
THAT WAS THE FIRST THING I
THOUGHT WAS TOO MANY AMBULANCES.
>> TOO MANY.
>> Reporter: SO I KNOW YOUR SON
WHO IS A FIRST GRADER, WHICH
MAKES HIM 7 YEARS OLD, ROUGHLY?
HE WAS IN THE ROOM VERY CLOSE TO
WHERE THE MAJORITY OF THE
SHOOTINGS HAPPENED.
>> HE WAS ONE TO TWO CLASSROOMS
AWAY.
>> Reporter: SO WHAT HAS HE TOLD
YOU SO FAR?
>> HE TOLD US THAT THEY WERE
LOOKING AT THE SMART BOARD AND
SOMETHING WENT WRONG, SO THE
TEACHER HAD THEM ALL SIT IN
THEIR CUBBIES.
AND THEY READ BOOKS IN THEIR
CUBBIES UNTIL POLICEMEN CAME.
AND HE SAID THE POLICEMEN SAID
JUST WALK VERY FAST.
AND HE SAID HE SAW SOME PEOPLE
ON THE FLOOR, SOMEONE ON THE
FLOOR, SLEEPING.
>> Reporter: SO WHEN HE RECOUNTS
THE STORY TO YOU, IS HE UPSET?
IS HE EMOTIONAL?
OR DO YOU THINK HE'S SO LITTLE,
6, HE DOESN'T QUITE PROCESS THE
SLEEPING OR HIS CLASSMATES?
>> WHEN I FIRST FOUND HIM IN THE
FIREHOUSE WHERE THEY HAD BROUGHT
THE CHILDREN, HE WAS IN VERY
GOOD SPIRITS, VERY TALKATIVE.
WHEN WE BROUGHT HIM AWAY FROM
THE FIREHOUSE, HE WAS VERY
TALKATIVE.
UNLIKE MY DAUGHTER, WHO WAS VERY
QUIET.
HE WAS VERY UPBEAT.
I DON'T THINK IT REALLY,
WHATEVER THE TEACHER DID, SHE
RELAXED THEM TO THE POINT THAT
THEY WERE UNAWARE OF WHAT WAS
GOING ON, WOULD BE MY
INTERPRETATION OF HIS REACTION.
>> Reporter: OR HOW MUCH DANGER
THEY WERE IN.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> Reporter: SHE HAD THEM HIDE
IN THEIR CUBBIES FOR AS MUCH
PROTECTION YOU COULD HAVE, WHICH
IS NOT MUCH IN A CUB BY.
>> WE REALIZED WHAT SHE PROBABLY
DID WAS SHE TOLD THEM THAT THE
MAGIC BOARD HAD MALFUNCTIONED
AND THAT WAS THE REASON THEY
NEEDED TO READ BOOKS IN THEIR
CUBBIE.
SHE READ TO THEM APPARENTLY
WHILE THIS WAS ALL GOING ON.
>> Reporter: THERE ARE SO MANY
STORIES OF THE TEACHERS BEING SO
HEROIC AND KEEPING SUCH A COOL
HEAD WHEN OBVIOUSLY EVERYTHING
WRONG IS GOING ON AROUND THEM.
PEOPLE DESCRIBE THE SHOOTING,
HEAR SCREAMING, AND THEIR JOB IS
TO KEEP A BUNCH OF SMALL
CHILDREN UNAWARE OF HOW BAD IT
REALLY IS.
THEY ARE REALLY TRUE HEROES.
>> THEY ARE SUPERHEROES.
WHEN WE WENT DOWN TO THE
FIREHOUSE TO GET OUR CHILDREN,
WE WERE UNAWARE OF THE REAL
TRAGEDY AT HAND.
I DID NOT THINK CHILDREN WERE
INVOLVED.
I THOUGHT THIS WAS ISOLATED, A
COUPLE TEACHERS, MAYBE EVEN JUST
ONE.
SO WHEN WE GOT OUR CHILDREN AND
I SAW MY SON'S TEACHER, THEY
WERE LIKE GHOSTS, BUT THEY WERE
INCREDIBLY COMPOSED.
THEY HAD THEIR SHEETS WITH THEM
CHECKING OFF TO MAKE SURE EACH
CHILD WENT WITH THEIR PARENT.
THEY -- THEY DID EVERYTHING
POSSIBLE TO KEEP OUR CHILDREN
SAFE.
EVERYTHING.
AND I WISH I HAD KNOWN WHEN I
LOOKED AT THEIR FACES JUST TO
SAY, THANK YOU.
BECAUSE I HAVE MY CHILDREN.
>> Reporter: A LOT OF PEOPLE
DON'T.
>> THEY DON'T.
>> IF I COULD HAVE GONE BACK,
LIKE MY WIFE SAID, WE HAD NO
IDEA AT THE LEVEL OF WHAT
HAPPENED IN THERE, THE RUMOR
GOING AROUND WAS THAT THE
PRINCIPAL WHO WAS A WONDERFUL,
BEAUTIFUL WOMAN, THE RUMOR WAS
THAT SHE HAD BEEN, THAT SHE HAD
BEEN KILLED.
AND ALL THE PARENTS HOPED THIS
WAS AN ISOLATED INCIDENT, EVEN
THOUGH THAT WAS A HORRIBLE LOSS
OF LIFE.
WHEN I SAW THOSE TEACHERS, WHEN
I FOUND THE TWO CHILDREN, AND WE
WERE DEVASTATED AND HEARTBROKEN
FOR THE POOR FAMILIES WHO DID
NOT HAVE THAT MOMENT IN THE
FIREHOUSE OF FINDING THEIR
CHILDREN.
WE CAN'T EVEN IMAGINE AND OUR
PRAYERS, JUST THE ENTIRE
COMMUNITY IS HEARTBROKEN.
BUT WHEN I SAW THE TEACHERS AND
I LOCKED EYES WITH EACH OF THEM
SEPARATELY, WHEN I FOUND THE TWO
CHILDREN, IF I COULD GO BACK, I
WOULD EMBRACE THEM.
BECAUSE I HAD NO IDEA WHAT THEY
HAD GONE THROUGH.
BUT IT WAS, IT WAS ACTUALLY
HANDLED VERY WELL BECAUSE I
CAN'T IMAGINE THE PANDEMONIUM
THAT WOULD HAVE BEEN GOING ON IN
THE FIREHOUSE WITH THE PARENTS
SEARCHING FOR THEIR CHILDREN.
IF ANYBODY THERE HAD ANY IDEA
THE LEVEL OF WHAT HAD HAPPENED
YESTERDAY, PEOPLE JUST SIMPLY
DIDN'T KNOW REALLY WHAT WAS
GOING ON.
THEY JUST KNEW THEIR CHILDREN
HAS BEEN IN A DANGEROUS PLACE
AND THOSE THAT MADE IT TO THE
FIREHOUSE WERE, THANK GOD, SAFE.
>> Reporter: WHAT WILL YOU TELL
YOUR SON WHO IS A FIRST GRADER?
WHAT WILL YOU TELL YOUR DAUGHTER
WHO IS A THIRD GRADE HER?
DO THEY HAVE ANY IDEA THE SCOOP
OF HOW BAD IT IS?
>> I THINK THEY DO MORE THAN
THEY ARE LETTING ON.
WE HAVE NOT SAID MUCH.
THIS IS SHOCKING.
SO THIS IS NEW TO US.
AND WE ARE DEFINITELY GOING TO
TALK TO COUNSELORS TODAY OVER AT
THE REED SCHOOL.
WE ARE GOING TO LIVE AT OUR
CHURCH, AT ST. ROSE, AND WE ARE
JUST GOING TO LEARN WHAT TO SAY
BEFORE WE SAY IT.
IT IS REALLY TRICKY.
AND FOR MY THIRD GRADER, LITTLE
BITS AND PIECES ARE COMING OUT
NOW.
>> Reporter: IT SOUNDS LIKE
SHE'S NOT TALKING AS MUCH ABOUT
IT.
>> LITTLE THINGS ARE COMING OUT
NOW WHERE SHE HEARD A LOT.
THEY ALL HEARD AND SAW THINGS
THAT OUR CHILDREN SHOULD NOT
HEAR OR SEE.
AND SO WE JUST, WE KNOW THAT IT
WAS A BAD MAN, AND WE JUST SAID
WE ARE COMING TO TALK TO PEOPLE
AND THEY WANT TO KNOW WHAT
HAPPENED AT SANDY HOOK.
THEY DON'T KNOW, THEY DON'T KNOW
THAT THEY HAVE LOST THEIR
FRIENDS AND THEIR PRINCIPAL.
>> IT'S BECOME APPARENT THAT OUR
6-YEAR-OLD HAS LOST CLOSE
FRIENDS.
AND HE'S VERY UNAWARE OF THAT
RIGHT NOW.
WE DON'T KNOW HOW TO EXACTLY
APPROACH IT WITH HIM AT THIS
POINT.
WE ARE JUST KIND OF GUARDING HIM
FROM THE TV.
WHEN THEY FELL ASLEEP LAST NIGHT
AND THE EXPERTS WOULD COME ON
THE TV TO DISCUSS HOW YOU TALK
TO YOUR CHILDREN, WE WERE VERY
ATTENTIVE LIKE, OH, LET'S LISTEN
FOR, LET'S WATCH THIS.
AND WE REALIZED WATCHING IT HAD
NOTHING TO DO WITH US.
IT HAD EVERYTHING TO DO WITH THE
REST OF THE COUNTRY WATCHING IT.
BUT NOT THE PEOPLE THAT WERE
INVOLVED AND THE CHILDREN THAT
WERE ACTUALLY INVOLVED IN THE
SCHOOL.
SO IT'S IMPORTANT FOR US TO
REALIZE AS THIS GOES ON TO TAKE
ADVANTAGE OF THE COUNSELING.
>> Reporter: MANY PEOPLE, SO
MANY PEOPLE HAVE SENT MESSAGES
TO ME TO TELL PEOPLE LIKE YOU
AND THE PEOPLE WHO HAVE LOST
THEIR CHILDREN, JUST HOW SORRY
THEY FEEL FOR THEM.
>> I MEAN, YOUR HEART, THIS IS A
FEELING THAT IS UNSPEAKABLE.
IT IS LIKE REACHING INTO YOUR
INSIDES AND PULLING THEM OUT.
I MEAN, WHEN THINGS HAPPEN TO
YOUR CHILDREN AND TO OTHER
PEOPLE'S CHILDREN, I CAN'T LOOK
AT MY CHILDREN'S FACES NOW
WITHOUT SEEING THE FACES OF
EVERY ONE OF THEIR SCHOOLMATES
AND EVERYTHING THEY ARE DOING
AND SAYING AND THINKING ABOUT
CHRISTMAS, I'M JUST THINKING,
THEIR FRIENDS SHOULD ALL BE
HERE.
AND IT IS JUST SUCH, IT IS SO
HEAVY.
SO HEAVY ON YOUR HEART.
AND --
>> Reporter: THE NATION FEELS
THAT WAY, TOO.
>> THE OUTPOURING OF LOVE HAS
BEEN TREMENDOUS.
I MEAN, PEOPLE ARE CALLING FROM
ALL OVER THE WORLD.
AND WE ARE GOING TO NEED THAT
NOW.
WE ARE GOING TO ABSOLUTELY NEED
THAT TO BE THERE AS A COMMUNITY.
WE LOVE SANDY HOOK.
THIS IS SUCH A GREAT PLACE.
AND THE PEOPLE ARE WONDERFUL.
AND WE ARE JUST GOING TO HAVE TO
REALLY EMBRACE EACH OTHER AND
OPEN OUR HEARTS AND OPEN OUR
ARMS AND OPEN THOSE CHURCH DOORS
AND JUST GET EVERYBODY PRAYING
AND TOGETHER.
BECAUSE, I MEAN, I THINK THIS IS
SOMETHING WE WILL GET THROUGH, I
DON'T THINK THIS IS SOMETHING WE
WILL EVER, EVER GET OVER.
>> I WOULD LIKE ALSO TO SAY THAT
WE ALWAYS FEEL BLESSED THAT OUR
CHILDREN WERE AT SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL.
IT IS A BEAUTIFUL SCHOOL,
FANTASTIC EDUCATORS.
THE PRINCIPAL WHO, GOD BLESS
HER, LOST HER LIFE.
SHE WAS JUST A VERY SPECIAL
PERSON.
AND ALL THE PARENTS KNEW THAT.
SO IT'S A VERY, IT'S A SHOCKING
THING BEYOND BELIEF THAT THIS
HAS HAPPENED AND THAT IT'S -- WE
ARE JUST HEARTBROKEN FOR THOSE
FAMILIES.
>> Reporter: WE ARE, TOO.
THANK YOU FOR TALKING TO US.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME.
SO YOU HEARD THERE'S TWO
CHILDREN IN THEIR FAMILY, A
THIRD GRADER AND FIRST GRADER.
THE FIRST GRADER WHO SEEMS TO
HAVE LOST NUMEROUS FRIENDS,
CLOSE FRIENDS.
I KNOW PARENTS HERE STRUGGLE
WITH THE CHALLENGE OF HOW TO
TELL THEIR CHILDREN THEIR
FRIENDS ARE DEAD AND OBVIOUSLY
THE PARENTS WHO HAVE LOST
CHILDREN STRUGGLE AS WELL WITH
HOW TO GO ON WITH THEIR LIVES.
A TERRIBLE STORY TO HAVE TO
COVER, A TERRIBLE STORY TO LIVE
THROUGH.
WE HAVE TO TAKE A SHORT BREAK.
AS I MENTIONED BEFORE, WE ARE
WAITING FOR THIS PRESS
CONFERENCE TO BEGIN.
THE STATE POLICE HAS BEEN REALLY
GOOD ABOUT UPDATING US ON THE
VERY LATEST IN THEIR PROCESS IN
THIS CASE.
THEY ARE A LITTLE DELAYED ON THE
PRESS CONFERENCE, AND IT IS
UNCLEAR WHY, BUT MAYBE WE'LL
HAVE A CHANCE TO UNDERSTAND WHY
THEY ARE WRAPPING THIS UP AND
DOING.
WE KNOW THEY WERE PROCESSING THE
SCENE INSIDE THE SCHOOL, WHICH
WAS TERRIBLE.
THEY WEREN'T GOING TO REMOVE THE
BODIES, INCLUDING THE BODY OF
THE SHOOTER AND THE BODIES OF
THE CHILDREN UNTIL THEY FINISHED
PROCESSING IT.
WHICH MEANT THE MEDICAL EXAMINER
WOULD BE INSIDE, WHICH MEANT
THEY WOULD CONTINUE TREATING IT
AS A CRIME SCENE.
UNTIL THEY WERE DONE, WHICH THEY
TOLD ME ORIGINALLY UNTIL SUNDAY,
NOTHING WOULD MOVE.
THEY WOULD NOT BE ABLE TO RETURN
THE BODIES TO THEIR PARENTS.
WE'LL TAKE A SHORT BREAK.
WHEN WE COME BACK, WE'LL UPDATE
YOU ON THE LATEST IN THE
INVESTIGATION, THE LATEST ON THE
SHOOTER, THE LATEST ON SERVICES
OFFERED TO THE PEOPLE HERE AND
ALSO INFORMATION FOR PEOPLE
STRUGGLING HOW TO TELL THEIR OWN
CHILDREN ABOUT THIS TERRIBLE
TRAGEDY, EVEN IF THEY ARE MILES
AND MILES AWAY FROM HERE.
WE'LL BE BACK RIGHT AFTER THIS.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
AS WE CONTINUE TOUR SPECIAL
COVERAGE OF THE CONNECTICUT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SHOOTING, LOTS
WE ARE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT THIS
MORNING.
WE ARE WAITING FOR A PRESS
CONFERENCE FROM THE STATE
POLICE.
THEY HAVE BEEN UPDATING US
THROUGHOUT THE LAST 24 HOURS OF
THIS ABSOLUTE TRAGEDY.
WE ARE EXPECTING THEM, AT LEAST
100 CAMERAS AND JOURNALISTS ARE
HERE NEXT TO ME.
WE ARE EXPECTING THE PRESS
CONFERENCE TO HAPPEN
MOMENTARILY.
WE KNOW THEY HAVE LOCKED DOWN
THE SCENE OF THE SCHOOL AND LEFT
EVERYTHING INSIDE AS IT WAS FOR
24 HOURS AGO, WHICH MEANS THEY
HAVE NOT MOVED ANY OF THE
BODIES.
AND WE ARE WAITING FOR THEM TO
UPDATE US ON THE LATEST OF THIS
CRIME SCENE.
OBVIOUSLY, THERE ARE MANY
PARENTS AND MANY PEOPLE WHO
WOULD LOVE TO HAVE THE BODIES OF
THOSE WHO HAVE DIED IN THIS
AWFUL TRAGEDY, TO HAVE THOSE
BODIES BACK TODAY.
SO IT BRINGS US TO THINK ABOUT
WHAT THE PARENTS OF THE VICTIMS
ARE GOING THROUGH THIS MORNING.
ABSOLUTELY A HORRIFIC SITUATION.
JUST A FEW MOMENTS AGO WE TALKED
TO A MOTHER AND FATHER OF A
FIRST GRADER AND THIRD GRADER.
THEY TOLD US THEY ARE ABSOLUTELY
GRAPPLING WITH WHAT TO DO AT
THIS POINT.
THEY REALLY DON'T KNOW WHAT TO
TELL THEIR CHILDREN.
IT'S THE SAME QUESTION THAT
PEOPLE WHO ARE NOWHERE NEAR THE
SCENE TODAY ACROSS THE COUNTRY
ARE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT AS
WELL.
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN TO SMALL
CHILDREN THAT THEIR SCHOOL, THAT
THEY ASSUME IS SAFE, IS NOT
NECESSARILY A SAFE PLACE?
I WANT TO START BY PLAYING A
LITTLE BIT OF THE RADIO
TRANSMISSIONS BETWEEN THE POLICE
AND THE 911 RESPONDERS.
WHAT WE KNOW NOW IS THAT IT IS
BELIEVED THAT, IN FACT, THERE
WAS A SECURITY SYSTEM AT THE
SCHOOL THAT WAS PUT IN PLACE BY
THE PRINCIPAL WHEN SHE ARRIVED
TWO YEARS AGO.
A PARENT TOLD ME THAT YESTERDAY.
WHAT WE KNOW IS THAT SOMEHOW THE
SHOOTER WAS ABLE TO GET PAST
THAT SECURITY SYSTEM.
THERE WAS SOME WHO DESCRIBED THE
GLASS AT THE FRONT DOOR AS SHOT
OUT AND THERE ARE SOME
SPECULATIONS THAT THAT WAS THE
WAY HE WAS ABLE TO GET AROUND
THE SECURITY SYSTEM.
LET'S PLAY A LITTLE BIT FOR YOU
OF THE 911 CALLS FIRST.
>> 6-7 SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
CALLER IS INDICATING SHE THINKS
SOMEBODY IS SHOOTING IN THE
BUILDING.
>> THE FRONT GLASS HAS BEEN
BROKEN.
THEY ARE UNSURE WHY.
ALL UNITS, THE INDIVIDUAL THAT I
HAVE ON THE PHONE IS CONTINUING
TO HEAR WHAT SHE BELIEVES IS DUN
FIRE.
UNITS RESPONDING TO SANDY HOOK
AT THIS TIME, THE SHOOTING
APPEARS TO HAVE STOPPED.
THE SCHOOL IS IN LOCKDOWN.
>> Reporter: ACCORDING TO LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS, THE
ACTUAL SHOOTING SEEMS TO HAVE
LASTED ONLY ABOUT TEN MINUTES.
BUT IN THAT TIME, AN ABSOLUTELY
TERRIBLE TOLL WOULD TAKE PLACE.
ANDERSON COOPER WALKS US THROUGH
THE TRAGEDY AND HOW IT UNFOLDED.
>> ALL UNITS, THE INDIVIDUAL I
HAVE OWN THE PHONE IS CONTINUING
TO HEAR WHAT SHE BELIEVES TO BE
GUNFIRE.
>> Reporter: THE FIRST WORD WAS
CHILLING.
IT ONLY GOT WORSE.
>> THEY ARE REPORTING MULTIPLE
FATALITIES INVOLVED AT THE
ALMOSTRY SCHOOL.
>> Reporter: WITH EACH NEW
REPORT, THE HORROR DEEPENED.
>> REPORTS DO SAY THE NUMBER OF
DEAD IS CLOSER TO 30 THAN 20 AND
SADLY MOST OF THEM ARE CHILDREN.
>> Reporter: EVERY DETAIL, EVERY
FACT BROUGHT MORE SADNESS.
EACH FRESH PIECE OF INFORMATION
A PART OF THE PICTURE, A SCHOOL,
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADE.
A SANCTUARY THAT WAS SUPPOSED TO
BE A PLACE OF SAFETY TORN APART.
>> SHE HEARD THE INTERCOM THAT
CAME ON IN THE SCHOOL AND SHE
HEARD A SCREAM AND A GUNSHOT,
TWO GUNSHOTS.
AND THEN THE SCHOOL WENT INTO
LOCKDOWN.
>> Reporter: A STUDENT'S
TEENAGER BIG BROTHER DESCRIBING
THE SOUNDS OF THE GUNMAN ON THE
LOOSE AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
>> THE FIRST RESPONDERS
RESPONDED TO THE SCHOOL AND WITH
NEWTOWN POLICE IMMEDIATELY UPON
ARRIVAL, THEY ENTERED THE SCHOOL
AND BEGAN A COMPLETE ACTIVE
SHOOTER SEARCH OF THE BUILDING.
>> Reporter: THEY ARRIVED TO
CARNAGE.
THE KILLER SAYS A LAW
ENFORCEMENT SOURCE WITH DETAILED
KNOWLEDGE WAS DRESSED FOR BATTLE
IN BLACK FATIGUES AND ARMED FOR
MASS MURDER WITH TWO PISTOLS AND
A MILITARY-STYLE RIFLE.
IN PARTS OF THE SCHOOL STUDENTS
WERE TOLD TO HIDE IN CORNERS.
TEACHERS RISKED THEIR OWN LIVES
TO PULL BOYS AND GIRLS TO
SAFETY.
>> I'M JUST SO GRATEFUL TO THE
TEACHER WHO SAVED HIM.
>> Reporter: YOU THINK THE
TEACHER SAVED HIS LIFE?
>> SHE DEFINITELY DID.
HE HAD BULLETS GOING BY HIM AND
SHE GRABBED HIM AND ANOTHER
CHILD AND PULLED THEM INTO A
CLASSROOM.
>> Reporter: EVENTUALLY THE KIDS
WERE EVACUATED TO A FIREHOUSE
WHERE FRANTIC PARENTS DESCENDED.
>> IT WAS TERRIFYING.
I'M STILL TERRIFIED AND IN
SHOCK.
I STILL DON'T KNOW EVERYTHING
THAT HAPPENED.
I KNOW THERE ARE SOME PEOPLE
MISSING AND TAKEN TO THE
HOSPITAL.
>> Reporter: I KNOW HIS SON WAS
OKAY.
HIS SON'S TEACHER WAS ALIVE AS
WELL.
20 OTHER CHILDREN AND 6 ADULTS
WERE KILLED.
THE DEAD INCLUDED TO INCLUDE
SANDY HOOK'S PSYCHOLOGIST AND
THE PRINCIPAL.
POLICE DISCOVERED ANOTHER ADULT
VICTIM, THE GUNMAN'S MOTHER
REPORTEDLY AT HOME IN NEWTOWN.
POLICE SAY THEY FIRED NO SHOTS.
A TIGHT-KNIT COMMUNITY INCLUDING
A NURSE WHO LIVED NEARBY TO
HELP, SHOCKED AND DISTRAUGHT.
I SEE YOU HAVE BEEN CRYING.
>> YES.
>> Reporter: IS IT BECAUSE OF
WHAT YOU SAW?
>> ONE OF THE COPS, THE WORST
THING HE HAD EVER SEEN IN HIS
ENTIRE CAREER, IT WAS WHEN THEY
TOLD THE PARENTS, ALL THESE
PARENTS WERE WAITING FOR THEIR
CHILDREN TO COME OUT.
THEY THOUGHT THEY WERE STILL
ALIVE.
THERE WAS 20 PARENTS JUST TOLD
THAT THEIR CHILDREN ARE DEAD.
IT WAS AWFUL.
>> Reporter: AWFUL.
AND LATE TODAY SPEAKING FOR THE
NATION BUT ALSO AS A FATHER, AN
EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT OBAMA FOUGHT
BACK TEARS.
>> THIS EVENING MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT EVERY PARENT IN
AMERICA WILL DO, WHICH IS HUG
OUR CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER
AND WE'LL TELL THEM THAT WE LOVE
THEM AND WE'LL REMIND EACH OTHER
HOW DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT.
AND THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT
NOW.
>> Reporter: THAT'S VERY TRUE.
THEY DO NEED ALL OF OUR SUPPORT
RIGHT NOW.
IF YOU WOULD LIKE MORE
INFORMATION ON HOW YOU CAN HELP
THOSE WHO ARE AFFECTED BY THE
SHOOTING, GO TO CNN.COM/IMPACT.
AND YOU CAN ABSOLUTELY REACH OUT
AND HELP IN ANY WAY THAT YOU
PROBABLY CAN.
YOU HEARD A FEW MOMENTS AGO THE
COUPLE WITH A FIRST GRADER AND
THIRD GRADE DAUGHTER AS WELL.
THEY DIDN'T KNOW EXACTLY WHAT TO
DO OR HOW TO TALK TO THEIR KIDS.
THEY ARE MEETING WITH COUNSELORS
TODAY IN THE COMMUNITY.
SO THE PARENTS HERE WHOSE
CHILDREN HAVE SURVIVED CAN HAVE
SOME KIND OF A SENSE OF WHAT TO
TELL THEIR CHILDREN.
THERE ARE MANY PARENTS WHO ARE
NOT IN THIS TOWN, OUTSIDE OF
THIS TOWN AND AROUND THE
COUNTRY, WHO ARE ALSO TRYING TO
FIGURE OUT THE SAME THING DO.
YOU TALK ABOUT IT OR NOT TALK
ABOUT IT?
DO YOU WATCH IT ON TV OR NOT LET
THEM WATCH IT UNFOLD ON TV?
WE'LL TALK TO A PSYCHIATRIST
ABOUT THE BEST WAY TO TALK TO
YOUR CHILDREN IN THE WAKE OF
THIS TRAGEDY.
WE ARE BACK IN JUST A MOMENT.
STAY WITH US.
♪
CO
LD ONLY COME FROM NATURE.
NOW FROM THE MAKER
OF SPLENDA SWEETENERS,
DISCOVER NECTRESSE.
THE ONLY 100% NATURAL,
NO-CALORIE SWEETENER
MADE FROM THE GOODNESS
OF FRUIT.
THE RICH, SWEET TASTE OF SUGAR.
NOTHING ARTIFICIAL.
♪
IT'S ALL THAT SWEET
EVER NEEDS TO BE.
NEW NECTRESSE.
SWEETNESS NATURALLY.
GIVES YOU 1% CASH BACK
ON ALL PURCHASES,