>>> GOOD AFTERNOON, EVERYONE.
I'M DON LEMON AND YOU'RE
WATCHING LIVE SPECIAL COVERAGE
FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, THE
SCENE OF THE HORRIFIC ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL RAMPAGE.
>> AND I'M DEBORAH FEYERICK HERE
LIVE IN ATLANTA.
>> I WANT TO TELL YOU, VIEWERS,
THIS IS HARD AND OVER THE NEXT
TWO HOURS KNOW THAT WE ARE DOING
SOMETHING THAT'S REALLY HARD AND
UNPRECEDENTED, NOT DEALING WITH
WHAT THE FAMILIES ARE DEALING
WITH, OBVIOUSLY, WHO HAVE
SUFFERED SUCH TRAGEDY BUT TO
HAVE TO COME AND REPORT ON 20
CHILDREN DEAD IS ALMOST UNFATE
TH
UNFATHOMABLE.
THE CHURCH IS KEEPING THEIR
DOORS OPEN AND ARE NOT ALLOWING
THE MEDIA TO COME IN HERE.
THIS SEARCH IS OPEN FOR 24
HOURS.
THEY HAVE LOST MEMBERS OF THEIR
OWN CHURCH.
AGAIN, THIS IS HARD.
I CAN SPEAK FOR MYSELF AND DEB
FEYERICK, WE WILL TRY TO SPEAK
AS CALM AND COMFORTING AS WE CAN
AND SOMETIMES WE WON'T GET
THINGS RIGHT.
WE'RE LEARNING A LOT OF
INFORMATION JUST AS YOU ARE
LEARNING IT HERE.
WE'RE GOING TO BE TRY TO BE AS
RESPECTFUL AS POSSIBLE.
WE DID NOT SPEAK WITH CHILDREN
ON CAMERA WITHOUT THE PARENTS'
PERMISSION.
AS WE SAY THAT, BEAR WITH US
HERE AND WE'RE GOING TO TRY TO
GO THROUGH THIS WITHOUT BREAKING
DOWN.
THIS IS REALLY TOUGH FOR
EVERYONE INVOLVED AND FOR
EVERYONE WATCHING.
SO WE'RE LEARNING NEW DETAILS
ABOUT HOW THIS RAMPAGE UNFOLDED
AND THAT MAN, WHO IS ACCUSED OF
CARRYING IT OUT.
HE IS 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA AND
WE WILL TRY TO SAY HIS NAME AS
LITTLE AS POSSIBLE BUT WE HAVE
TO SAY IT FOR THE RECORD.
LANZA TRIED TO BUY A GUN THREE
DAYS BEFORE THE SHOOTING BUT DID
NOT HAVE THE PROPER PAPERWORK.
AND POLICE REVEALED JUST TODAY
THAT THREE GUNS, NOT TWO, AS
PREVIOUSLY THOUGHT WERE FOUND
NEAR LANZA'S BODY INSIDE THAT
SCHOOL.
INVESTIGATORS ARE WORKING AROUND
THE CLOCK AND WILL PROBABLY BE
THERE FOR ANOTHER DAY OR TWO
UNTIL THEY GET ALL OF THE
INFORMATION THEY NEED.
THE VICTIMS' BODIES HAVE BEEN
REMOVED FROM THE SCHOOL AND
TAKEN TO THE MEDICAL EXAMINER'S
OFFICE.
NOT JUST VICTIMS BUT PEOPLE WHO
LIVED EXTRAORDINARY LIVES.
THEIR NAMES ARE EXPECTED TO BE
RELEASED SOON.
AND WHEN WE GET THEM WE WILL
REVEAL THEM TO YOU AS RESPECTFUL
AS POSSIBLE.
WE'RE LEFT WITH MORE QUESTIONS
THAN ANSWERS ABOUT THE POSSIBLE
MOTIVE OF THIS 20-YEAR-OLD
SHOOTER.
POLICE SAY HE KILLED HIS MOTHER.
HIS MOTHER'S NAME IS NANCY.
HE DID THAT AT HER HOME IN
NEWTOWN BEFORE THE RAMPAGE AT
SCHOOL AND THEN TOOK HIS OWN
LIVE.
MARY SNOW IS LIVE.
THIS IS TOUGH.
WHAT HAVE WE LEARNED ABOUT THIS
SUSPECT?
ARE WE LEARNING ANYTHING ABOUT A
MOTIVE AT THIS HOUR?
>> Reporter: WELL, DON,
OFFICIALS AREN'T SAYING PUBLICLY
WHAT THEY ARE SAYING ABOUT A
MOTIVE BUT THEY ARE PICKING UP
INFORMATION ABOUT HOW AND WHY
THIS HORRIC SHOOTING HAPPENED
AND THEY HAVE BEEN RECOVERING
EVIDENCE AND WE JUST SAW A TRUCK
BELONGING TO THE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE JUST LEAVING THE
LANZA HOME THAT IS BEHIND ME.
YOU CAN'T SEE IT.
IT'S BEHIND ME AT THE BACK.
SEVERAL LAW ENFORCEMENT VEHICLES
LEFT JUST MOMENTS AGO AND LAW
ENFORCEMENT HAS BEEN ON THIS
SCENE SINCE SHORTLY AFTER
YESTERDAY'S HORRIFIC SHOOTING.
EARLIER THIS MORNING LIEUTENANT
PAUL VANCE WAS ASKED WHETHER
WRITINGS OR E-MAILS WERE
RECOVERED TO TELL INVESTIGATORS
ABOUT A POTENTIAL MOTIVE.
HERE'S HOW HE ANSWERED THAT
QUESTION.
>> OUR INVESTIGATORS AT THE
CRIME SCENE, THE SCHOOL AND
SECONDARILY AT THE SECONDARY
CRIME SCENE THAT WE DISCUSSED
WHERE THE FEMALE WAS LOCATED
DECEASED, DID PRODUCE SOME VERY
GOOD EVIDENCE IN THIS
INVESTIGATION THAT OUR
INVESTIGATORS WILL BE ABLE TO
USE IN HOPEFULLY PAINTING THE
COMPLETE PICTURE ABOUT HOW AND
WHY THIS OCCURRED.
>> Reporter: DON, YOU WERE JUST
REPORTING ON THE WEAPONS THAT
WERE FOUND YESTERDAY NEAR THE
SHOOTER'S BODY.
CNN -- THOSE TWO WEAPONS, TWO
HANDGUNS AND ONE SEMIAUTOMATIC
RIFLE AND CNN HAS BEEN REPORTING
THAT THE WEAPONS HAD BEEN
PURCHASED BY THE SUSPECT'S
MOTHER, NANCY LANZA.
NANCY LANZA, DON'T KNOW MUCH
ABOUT HER.
WE DID TALK TO A NEIGHBOR
EARLIER TODAY WHO SAID, BE YOU
KNOW, THERE WAS NOTHING OUT OF
THE ORDINARY ABOUT THIS WOMAN,
THAT SHE WAS A NICE WOMAN.
SHE WAS KNOWN AROUND THE
NEIGHBORHOOD.
BUT SAID THAT THE FAMILY WASN'T
ALL THAT SOCIAL BUT THERE WAS
REALLY NOTHING OUT OF THE
ORDINARY AND CAME AS A SURPRISE
TO LEARN ABOUT THOSE WEAPONS,
OBVIOUSLY.
DON?
>> SO MARY, AS WE ARE LEARNING,
ONE WAS A GLOCK, ONE WAS A SIG
SAUER AND ONE WAS A BUSHMASTER
AND WE UNDERSTAND HE TRIED TO
PURCHASE OTHER GUNS BUT THERE
WAS AN ISSUE WITH THE PAPERWORK?
>> Reporter: CNN'S SUSAN
CANDIOTTI HAD BEEN REPORTING
ABOUT THE FACT THAT HE HAD
ACCESS TO OTHER WEAPONS AND THAT
THERE HAD BEEN, I BELIEVE, THREE
OTHER WEAPONS WERE RECOVERED
ELSEWHERE.
>> AND YOU LOOK AT THOSE GUNS ON
THE SCREEN.
MARY, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YOU WONDER HOW A 20-YEAR-OLD WHO
MAY HAVE HAD ISSUES WOULD GAIN
ACCESS TO THOSE GUNS AND EVERY
TIME WE HAVE A SHOOTING I JUST
CAME BACK FROM COLORADO IT SEEMS
LIKE WEEKS AGO REPORTING ON THAT
THEATER SHOOTING.
WHEN IS THE TIME, MARY?
WHEN IS THE TIME?
THAT'S WHAT EVERYONE AROUND THE
COUNTRY IS WONDERING.
THANK YOU, MARY SNOW.
DEB FEYERICK IS BACK IN ATLANTA
WHERE WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT
THE VICTIMS.
DEB?
>> ONE THING TO CONTINUE ON YOUR
TRAIN OF THOUGHT, THE THREE GUNS
THAT WERE FOUND, THREE OF THEM
WERE PURCHASED LEGALLY BY THE
MOTHER, NANCY LANZA.
THE QUESTION IS, WHY DID SHE
HAVE THESE PARTICULAR TYPE OF
GUNS WHICH ARE DEFENSIVE.
THESE ARE NOT HUNTING RIFLES.
THESE ARE GUNS THAT YOU KEEP FOR
PROTECTION.
CLEARLY THAT IS SOMETHING THAT
THEY ARE GOING TO BE LOOKING
INTO.
WE ARE LEARNING ABOUT THE NAMES
OF THE VICTIMS OF THIS HORRIFIC
ATTACK.
20 CHILDREN.
THEY WERE BETWEEN THE AGES OF 5
AND 10 YEARS OLD, FROM
KINDERGARTEN UP TO 3rd AND 4th
GREAT.
SIX ADULTS KILLED, AMONG THE
SCHOOL'S PRINCIPAL AND SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST.
NICK VALENCIA IS JOINING ME AS
HE IS LEARNING MORE ABOUT WHO
THE VICTIMS ARE.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
WE'RE WAITING FOR A CONFIRMATION
FROM STATE POLICE.
26 PEOPLE IN ALL KILLED AT THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
YESTERDAY.
WE HAVE BEEN ABLE TO
INDEPENDENTLY CONFIRM TWO OF
THOSE NAMES, DEB.
ONE IS DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, THE
BELOVED PRINCIPAL.
JUST 47 YEARS OLD.
SHE HAD BEEN THE PRINCIPAL SINCE
2010.
DESCRIBED BY PEOPLE WHO KNEW HER
AS AFFABLE BUT SERIOUS LEADER.
A TOUGH LADY BUT IN THE RIGHT
SORT OF SENSE.
SHE HAD ARRIVED WITH 12 YEARS OF
ADMINISTRATIVE SPERN.
SHE HAS A BEAUTIFUL SMILE.
SHE OVERSAW THE SCHOOL SECURITY
PROJECT WHICH REQUIRED EVERYBODY
THAT VISITED THE SCHOOL AFTER
9:30 A.M., THEY WERE REQUIRED TO
BUZZ IN AT THAT FRONT ENTRANCE.
WE UNDERSTAND THAT DETAILS HAVE
EMERGED THAT THE GUNMAN STORMED
IN, FORCED HIS WAY IN TO SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
SHE WAS -- GETTING BA BEING ACK
THE VICTIM, DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, SHE
LEAVES BEHIND A HUSBAND AND TWO
DAUGHTERS AND THREE
STEPDAUGHTERS.
MARY SHERLACH, THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST, SHE SPENT A LOT OF
TIME IN THREE SCHOOL SYSTEMS
BEFORE ARRIVING AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENT VEE SCHOOL.
ON FRIDAY, A PARENT TOLD CNN
THAT SHERLACH AND HOCHSPRUNG
WERE IN AN ADMINISTRATIVE
MEETING AT WHICH POINT THEY
HEARD A LARGE POP, POP, POP
WHICH WE NOW UNDERSTAND WAS THE
GUNFIRE COMING FROM THE
SUSPECTED GUNMAN AT WHICH POINT
THEY LEFT INTO THE HALLWAY AND
THEY WERE CONFRONTED BY THE
GUNMAN.
THEY LEFT TO INVESTIGATE BUT
BOTH NEVER CAME BACK.
THE PSYCHOLOGIST, MARY SHERLACH,
HAD A MASTER'S DEGREE FROM
SOUTHERN STATE CONNECTICUT.
SHE WORKED WITH DISABLED ADULTS.
A QUINTESSENTIAL IN THAT FABRIC
OF THE COMMUNITY THERE.
A SAD, SAD SITUATION.
THE 26 VICTIMS, TWO NAMES WE'VE
BEEN ABLE TO CONFIRM SO FAR.
WE'LL UNDOUBTEDLY HEAR MORE
ABOUT THE VICTIMS.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
AND KATE BOLDUAN REPORTED THAT A
TEACHER WAS ABLE TO PROTECT HER
CHILDREN AND THEY RAN OUT PAST
THE GUNMAN.
IT'S NOT CLEAR WHETHER IN FACT
SHE SURVIVED THIS ATTACK.
HER SISTER POSTED SOMETHING ON
HER TWITTER ACCOUNT SAYING MY
SISTER DIED PROTECTING HER
STUDENTS.
GOD, WHY DID YOU TAKE HER?
AND DON I THINK THAT IS THE
QUESTION THAT SO MANY ARE
REQUESTING NOW WHEN YOU LOOK AT
THE FACES AND WE'RE GOING TO SEE
SO MANY OTHER FACES.
BUT WHEN YOU LOOK AT THIS AND
YOU THINK OF THE VULNERABILITY
AND HOW ONE MOMENT YOU ARE HAPPY
AND YOUR LIFE IS IN TACT AND
THEN ALL OF A SUDDEN IT'S ALMOST
AS IF YOU TAKE A TURN AND YOU GO
DOWN ANOTHER PATH AND I THINK
THAT IS A QUESTION THAT EVERYONE
IS GOING TO ASK AND THAT IS,
GOD, WHY DID YOU TAKE THEM?
DON?
>> WE KEEP CALLING THEM VICTIMS.
THESE ARE PEOPLE WHO LIVED
EXTRAORDINARY LIVES AND IF
YOU'VE HEARD THEIR STORY, YOU'VE
HEARD HOW THEY HANDLE ALL OF
THIS EXTRAORDINARY PEOPLE WHO
DID THE BEST THAT THEY COULD
UNDER THESE CIRCUMSTANCES AND
I'M SURE CIRCUMSTANCES IN THEIR
LIVES AND I WOULD NOT LIKE TO
TROEFR THEM AS VICTIMS.
JUST PEOPLE WHO LIVED
EXTRAORDINARY LIVES AND TAKEN
AWAY TOO SOON.
THANK YOU, DEB.
>>> NEW INFORMATION JUST IN TO
CNN, THE GOVERNOR DANNEL MALLOY,
THE GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT,
WILL ADDRESS THE PEOPLE OF
CONNECTICUT AT 5:00 P.M.
EASTERN.
HE WILL SPEAK TO THE PEOPLE OF
CONNECTICUT LIVE FROM HIS
OFFICE.
IT GOES ON TO SAY HOW WE'RE
GOING TO GET THE INFORMATION.
EXPECT THAT AND WE'LL CARRY IT
LIVE FOR YOU HERE IN CNN.
IN THE MEANTIME, INVESTIGATORS
SAY THAT THE SCHOOL SHOOTER HAD
SOME SORT OF ALTERCATION AT THE
SCHOOL EARLIER IN THE WEEK AND
POLICE NOW SAY TWO PISTOLS AND
AN ASSAULT RIFLE WERE FOUND
INSIDE THE SCHOOL NEAR HIS BODY.
NO ONE, ESPECIALLY LITTLE KIDS,
ESPECIALLY LITTLE KIDS -- THINK
ABOUT THE AGE OF THESE CHILDREN.
NO ONE STANDS A CHANCE AGAINST
SUCH FIRE POWER.
I WANT TO BRING IN CNN
CONTRIBUTOR AND FORMER CIA
DIRECTOR TOM FUENTES.
BEFORE WE GET TO THAT
CONVERSATION, LET'S TALK ABOUT
THE CONVERSATION THAT PEOPLE ARE
HAVING IN THE COUNTRY WHEN IT
COMES TO GUN LAWS AND THE SECOND
AMENDMENT RIGHT.
NO ONE IS TRYING TO TAKE AWAY
THE SECOND AMOUNT RIGHT.
AS A TAX DEE DRIVER DROVE ME TO
MY HOTEL AT 5:00 IN THE MORNING,
THE TAXI DRIVER SAID, WHAT IS
CONGRESS DOING ABOUT GUN LAWS?
IT'S TIME TO ACT NOW AND STOP
SAYING IT'S NOT RESPONSIBLE TO
TALK ABOUT IT AFTER A SHOOTING.
THIS IS THE TIME TO TALK ABOUT
IT.
>> DON, I COMPLETELY AGREE WITH
YOU.
WE HEAR WE CAN'T TALK ABOUT THIS
NOW, WE HAVE TO BE IN MOURNING
AND PRAY FOR THE FAMILIES AND
THEN A COUPLE DAYS GO BY, THE
EMOTION GOES BY AND NOBODY CARES
TO TALK ABOUT IT.
SO YOU'RE RIGHT.
WHEN IS THE TIME?
THERE'S NO GOOD TIME.
NO BETTER TIME THAN THE PRESENT,
I THINK, TO HAVE AT LEAST HAVE
THE DISCUSSION OF WHAT IS
REASONABLE FOR THE NUMBER OF
FIREARMS THAT ARE AT LARGE IN
SOCIETY AND NOT TO MENTION THAT
WE STILL HAVE THE ISSUE OF THE
VERY INADEQUATE MENTAL HEALTH
SYSTEM IN THIS COUNTRY.
SO IF YOU'RE A PARENT AND HAVE A
CHILD THAT IS GROWING UP WITH
PROBLEMS AND YOU CAN SEE THAT
THEY HAVE SOME TYPE OF A BRAIN
DISORDER OR MENTAL ISSUE,
THERE'S NOT MUCH THAT YOU CAN DO
ABOUT IT.
THERE'S NOT MUCH HELP THAT
SOCIETY GIVES A FAMILY OR LAW
ENFORCEMENT OR DOCTORS TO DEAL
WITH MENTALLY DISTURBED
INDIVIDUALS AND THEN COMBINE
THAT WITH THE NUMBER OF WEAPONS
AT LARGE AND WE HAVE DISASTER
AFTER DISASTER.
WE'RE ALL UPSET, SHOCKED AND
OUTRAGED.
A COUPLE DAYS GO BY AND NOTHING
CHANGES.
>> WELL, LISTEN, I THINK YOU'RE
RIGHT ABOUT THAT WHEN IT COMES
TO THE MENTAL HEALTH ISSUE.
HERE'S THE THING.
IF SOMEONE HAS A MENTAL HEALTH
PROBLEM, THREE OTHER PEOPLE, TEN
OTHER PEOPLE CAN TAKE THEM DOWN.
IF SOMEONE WITH A KNIFE DOES THE
SAME THING, THAT DOES NOT HAPPEN
WITH A GUN.
YOU HAVE THE POWER WITH AN
AUTOMATIC WEAPON TO TAKE AWAY
MANY, MANY LIVES IN A SPLIT
SECOND AND THAT NEEDS TO BE
ADDRESSED, EVEN IF YOU ARE
MENTALLY HEALTHY OR MENTALLY
UNHEALTHY.
GUNS DO OFFER YOU THAT POWER.
>> WELL, THAT'S TRUE.
BUT IN THIS CASE, EVEN MORE
POWER BECAUSE --
>> AND IF YOU DIDN'T HAVE ACCESS
TO THOSE GUNS, MENTALLY STABLE
OR MENTALLY UNSTABLE, THEN
PEOPLE WOULD NOT BE ABLE TO TAKE
SO MANY LIVES AT ONCE.
>> WELL, THAT'S TRUE.
AND IN A CASE LIKE THIS, THOUGH,
WHERE THE SHOOTER STOPS AND
RELOADS, UNDOUBTEDLY TO FIRE AS
MANY BULLETS AS HE DID, HE WOULD
HAVE HAD TO RELOAD SEVERAL
TIMES.
WHO IS GOING TO ATTACK HIM OR
JUMP ON HIM?
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO HAVE A
5-YEAR-OLD SAY, LET'S ROLL AND
TAKE THE GUN AWAY FROM THE
SHOOTER.
IT'S NOT GOING TO HAPPEN.
THEY ARE GOING TO SIT THERE OR
STAND THERE OR RUN THERE AND BE
KILLED AND THAT'S WHAT WE HAVE
IN THIS CASE.
>> OKAY.
SO LISTEN, NOW WE'RE LEARNING
THAT THE GUNMAN MAY HAVE HAD
ACCESS TO THREE ADDITIONAL
RIFLES.
HE TRIED TO BUY A GUN AS EARLY
AS TUESDAY.
WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF THAT.
>> WELL, THAT'S INTERESTING.
WHAT WAS GOING ON IN HIS BRAIN
THAT HE DIDN'T THINK THE THREE
WEAPONS THAT HE SHOWED UP WITH
WERE ENOUGH?
A BLOCK, A SIG SAUER PISTOL, BE
TREMENDOUS FIREPOWER AND THEN
COMBINING THAT WITH AN ASSAULT
RIFLE WHERE HE CAN BUY A
30-ROUND OR GREATER MAGAZINE TO
FEED THROUGH THAT GUN?
THAT WASN'T ENOUGH?
WHAT DID HE HAVE IN MIND?
TAKE OUT THE WHOLE SCHOOL?
WE DON'T KNOW.
>> WHY ARE INVESTIGATORS SO
INTENT ON RECITING THE CRIME
FROM THE BEGINNING TO THE END?
IS IT LIKELY THAT THEY WILL
DISCOVER SOMETHING NEW?
>> IT'S POSSIBLE AND THEN ALSO
IN DOING HIS BACKGROUND CHECK
THEY MAY FIND THAT THERE MAY BE
SOME OTHER INDIVIDUAL OUT THERE
THAT TRIGGERED THIS AND WE DON'T
KNOW, NOT NECESSARILY A
CO-CONSPIRATOR BUT SOMEBODY OUT
THERE THAT MAY HAVE KNOWLEDGE
ABOUT IT AND THEY ARE GOING TO
WANT TO KNOW IF HE HAD PAPERWORK
ON HIS BODY WHEN THEY FOUND HIM
IN THE SCHOOL, MAYBE HE WROTE
SOME KIND OF MAN GUEIFESTO, GOOE
LETTER.
NO CLUE WHAT WAS ON HIS MIND.
BUT THE AUTHORITIES WANT TO TALK
TO EVERYBODY THAT'S HAD A
CONVERSATION WITH HIM OR DEALT
WITH HIM GOING BACK AS FAR AS
THEY CAN, DAYS, MONTHS, YEARS
EVEN TO SEE IF THERE WAS
SOMETHING THAT SHOWED UP IN THE
PAST THAT WOULD BE AN INDICATION
OF WHAT TRIGGERED THIS, WHY HE
WANTED TO DO IT, FOR THE
PURPOSES OF TRYING TO IDENTIFY
THAT SAME ISSUE IN OTHER PEOPLE
IN THE FUTURE.
>> TOM FUENTES, I REALLY THANK
YOU FOR YOUR CANDOR AND FOR
HAVING THE CONVERSATION WITH ME
THAT EVERYONE IS HAVING IN THIS
COUNTRY RIGHT NOW AND THEY WANT
TO SEE SOMETHING DONE ABOUT
THIS, NO MATTER HOW YOU FEEL
ABOUT GUN LAWS AND SECOND
AMENDMENT RIGHTS, IT'S SOMETHING
THAT EVERYONE FEELS NEEDS TO BE
LOOKED AT.
THANK YOU FOR HAVING THAT
CONVERSATION.
FOR MORE INFORMATION ON HOW TO
HELP THOSE AFFECTED BY THE
SHOOTING, GO TO CNN.COM/IMPACT.
BECAUSE OF SOCIAL MEDIA NOW, THE
PROLIFERATION OF SOCIAL MEDIA,
PEOPLE ARE GOING ONLINE TO SHARE
THEIR GRIEF AND OUTRAGE AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENT REE.
OUR iREPORTERS HAVE BEEN SENDING
IN MOVING COMMENTARY.
JOSH LEVS IS MONITORING ALL OF
IT FOR US.
I CAN ONLY IMAGINE WHAT YOU'RE
SEEING ON SOCIAL MEDIA.
>> PEOPLE ARE TALKING ABOUT GUN
LAWS.
I WANT TO SHARE SOMETHING WITH
YOU THAT WAS POSTED ON FACEBOOK
BY CAPTAIN MARK KELLY, HUSBAND
OF GABBY GIFFORDS.
THAT'S A FAMILY THAT KNOWS A LOT
ABOUT THE KIND OF TRAGEDIES THAT
CAN HAPPEN ON AN OTHERWISE
BEAUTIFUL DAY THAT TURNS INTO
CARNAGE.
LET'S LOOK A STATEMENT THAT HE
HAS PUT INTO FACEBOOK.
HE SAYS, AS WE MOURN, WE MUST
SOUND A CALL FOR OUR LEADERS TO
STAND UP AND DO WHAT IS RIGHT.
THIS TIME OUR RESPONSE MUST
CONSIST OF MORE THAN REGRET,
SORROW, AND CONDOLENCE.
THE CHILDREN OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND ALL
VICTIMS OF GUN VIOLENCE DESERVE
LEADERS WHO HAVE THE COURAGE TO
PARTICIPATE IN A MEANINGFUL
DISCUSSION ABOUT OUR GUN LAWS.
AND THAT'S AN EXAMPLE OF
DISCUSSIONS AMONG PEOPLE YOU
KNOW AND AROUND THE COUNTRY AND
AROUND THE WORLD RAISING
QUESTIONS WITH A SPECIAL FOCUS
ON GUN LAWS AND AT THE SAME TIME
BEING DRIVEN BY A LOT OF PASSION
AND INTENSE EMOTIONS ABOUT WHAT
WE'RE ALL GOING THROUGH.
THIS EXPERIENCE TRAUMATIZED
PEOPLE EVERYWHERE.
PARENT LIKE ME AND PEOPLE OF ALL
AGES AND STRIPES.
ONE OF THE PEOPLE WHO WEIGHED IN
IS AN iREPORTER WHO SENT US THIS
VIDEO.
HE'S IN WASHINGTON, D.C.
HE HAS DAUGHTERS AND HE WAS
ACTUALLY PICKING UP ONE OF HIS
KIDS AT SCHOOL WHEN HE HEARD THE
NEWS.
HERE'S PART OF WHAT HE SAYS.
>> THERE ARE SO MANY QUESTIONS
RIGHT NOW, MORE QUESTIONS THAN
ANSWERS.
BUT WHAT I DO KNOW IS THAT WE
NEED TO FIND SOME WAY TO COME
TOGETHER AROUND ALL VICTIMS OF
VIOLENCE, NOT JUST AT THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THAT IS THE TRANL JIK NEWS OF
THE DAY BUT REALLY FIGURE OUT
WHAT WE CAN DO TO SAVE OUR
CHILDREN AND MAKE THEM FEEL
SAFE.
>> I'M TALKING WITH YOU ON
FACEBOOK.
JOSHLEVS@CNN.COM.
THIS IS A PHOTO SPREAD OF PEOPLE
MOURNING ALL OVER THE WORLD.
SOME OF THESE PICTURES FROM ALL
OVER CONNECTICUT.
THIS ONE IS IN RIO.
YOU WILL SEE THAT THERE ARE MANY
PICTURES OF PEOPLE ALL OVER THE
WORLD HOLDING VIGILS, SHARING
THE SADNESS.
THE ONE ACT OF ONE PERSON THAT
DESTROYED LIVES, SHATTERED A
COMMUNITY, HAS SHATTERED
MILLIONS AND THESE EMOTIONS ARE
BEING SHARED ALL OVER THE WORLD.
WE ARE HEARING YOU.
DON, I'LL BE WITH YOU LATER WITH
THE LATEST ON THE INVESTIGATION.
>> JOSH LEVS, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
AND I HAVE WITNESSED IT ON THE
FACES OF PEOPLE HERE.
I HAVE NOT SEEN PEOPLE WHO,
QUITE HONESTLY, LOOKED LIKE THIS
SINCE I SAW THE RESCUE WORKERS
OF 9/11.
JUST A BLANK AND STUNNED LOOK ON
PEOPLE'S FACES AS THEY TRY TO GO
ON WITH THEIR LIVES IN LIGHT OF
THE HORRIFIC INCIDENT.
>>> TRAUMATIZED PARENTS AND
CHILDREN HAVE HORRIFYING DETAILS
OF THE CONNECTICUT SHOOTING.
WE HAVE ALL OF THOSE DETAILS FOR
YOU.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS AMY. AMY LIKES
TO INVEST IN THE MARKET.
SHE ALSO LIKES
TO RIDE HER BIKE.
SHE KNOWS THE POTENTIAL
FOR MAKING OR LOSING MONEY
CAN POP UP ANYTIME.
THAT'S WHY SHE TRADES WITH
THE LEADER IN MOBILE TRADING.
SO SHE'S ALWAYS READY
TO TAKE ACTION,
NO MATTER HOW WILY...
OR WEIRD...
OR WONDERFULLY
THE MARKET'S BEHAVING...
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
>>> THE DEADLY SHOOTING HERE IN
CONNECTICUT HAS CHANGED THE
LIVES OF SOME ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
CHILDREN FOREVER.
AND AS THE KIDS FROM SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, AS THEY RUSH
INTO THE ARMS OF FRANTIC
PARENTS, MANY OF THEM RECALL THE
CHAOS AND THE FEAR THEY HAD
WITNESSED JUST A FEW MOMENTS
AGO.
OUR BRIAN TODD HAS THE DETAILS.
>> Reporter: THE ACCOUNT OF A
YOUNG BOY SAID TO BE DELIVERING
AN ATTENDANCE REPORT TO THE
OFFICE WHEN THE SHOOTINGS TOOK
PLACE IS SURREAL.
>> I SAW SOME OF THE BULLETS
GOING PAST THE HALL THAT I WAS
RIGHT NEXT TO AND THEN A TEACHER
PULLED ME INTO HER CLASSROOM.
>> Reporter: HE SAID HE HEARD A
SOUND LIKE SOMEONE KICKING A
DOOR.
HIS MOTHER, CLINGING TO HIM, HAD
WORDS OF THANKS.
>> I'M JUST SO GRATEFUL TO THE
TEACHER WHO SAVED HIM.
>> Reporter: YOU THINK THE
TEACHER SAVED HIS LIFE?
>> HE DEFINITELY DID.
HE HAD BULLETS GOING BY HIM AND
SHE GRABBED HIM AND OTHER CHILD
AND PULLED THEM INTO A QUESTION.
>> Reporter: BRENDAN MURRAY, A
FOURTH GRADER, DESCRIBED THE
CHAOS.
>> I WAS IN THE GYM AT THE TIME.
WE HEARD LIKE LOTS OF BANGS AND
WE THOUGHT IT WAS THE KUFT CAN
STOED GENERAL KNOCKING THINGS
DOWN.
WE HEARD SCREAMING.
AND SO WE -- WE WENT -- LIKE WE
WENT TO THE WALL AND WE SAT DOWN
AND THEN A POLICE CAME IN AND
SAID, IS HE IN HERE?
AND THEN HE RAN OUT AND THEN
SOMEBODY YELLED, GET TO A SAFE
PLACE.
SO WE WENT INTO THE CLOSET IN
THE GYM AND WE SAT THERE FOR A
LITTLE WHILE AND THEN THE POLICE
LIKE WERE KNOCKING ON THE DOOR
AND THEY WERE LIKE, WE'RE
EVACUATING PEOPLE, WE'RE
EVACUATING PEOPLE.
>> Reporter: CNN IS ONLY AIRING
SOUNDS OF CHILDREN WHOSE PARENTS
GAVE THEM PERMISSION.
ONE WAS HEARD CRYING, WHY, WHY?
A POLICEMAN WAS HEARD SAYING IT
WAS THE WORST THING HE HAD SEEN
IN HIS CAREER.
A NURSE FROM NEARBY DANBURY
HOSPITAL DESCRIBED THE SCENE
THERE AS PARENT WAITED FOR WORD
FROM THEIR CHILDREN.
>> ALL OF THESE PARENTS WERE
WAITING FOR THEIR CHILDREN TO
COME OUT.
THEY THOUGHT THAT THEY WERE
STILL ALIVE.
THERE WERE 20 PARENTS THAT WERE
JUST TOLD THAT THEIR PARENTS
WERE DEAD.
IT WAS AWFUL.
>> Reporter: THE FATHER OF A
YOUNG GIRL WHO SURVIVED WAS JUST
TRYING TO PROCESS IT ALL.
>> IT WAS SHOCKING.
I GOT THE CALL AT WORK THIS
MORNING AND I CAN'T BELIEVE A
SMALL TOWN LIKE THIS WOULD HAVE
SOMETHING LIKE THIS HAPPEN AND
TO BE IN AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IS
UNHEARD OF.
>> Reporter: BY LATE FRIDAY
MORNING AND INTO THE EVENING
EVACUATED CHILDREN WERE BEING
CARED FOR AND REUNITING WITH
THEIR PARENTS AT A NEARBY
FIREHOUSE.
BRIAN TODD, CNN, WASHINGTON.
>> WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THE
CHILDREN IN WHAT DO YOU SAY TO
THEM?
FIVE YEARS AGO THIS WAS THE
SCENE AT NEW LIFE CHURCH IN
COLORADO SPRINGS.
A GUNMAN OPENED FIRE DURING A
CHURCH SERVICE AND KILLED TWO
TEENAGE SISTERS.
IT IS SOMETHING THAT PASTOR BOYD
UNDERSTANDS.
HE'S THE AUTHOR OF "FEAR IN
EVIL," A TEST OF FAITH.
PASTOR BOYD, THANK YOU FOR
JOINING US ON REALLY THIS
TERRIBLE, TERRIBLE TIME FOR THE
COUNTRY.
CAN YOU HEAL FROM THIS?
>> YES, YOU CAN.
THAT'S THE GOOD NEWS.
RIGHT NOW I CAN'T MANUAL.
I HAVE TWO KIDS OF MY OWN.
I CAN'T IMAGINE THE PAIN THOSE
PARENTS ARE FEELING AND RIGHT
NOW THEY ARE NUMB AND WE HAVE
EXPERIENCED HEALING,
RESTORATION, WE'RE SMILING
AGAIN, LAUGHING AGAIN.
IT TAKES A REALLY LONG TIME.
I WANT TO ENCOURAGE THE PEOPLE
OF CONNECTICUT TO BE THERE FOR
THESE FAMILIES MONTHS FROM NOW,
YEARS FROM NOW.
IT'S GOING TO TAKE A WHILE FROM
NOW, MAYBE YEARS FOR THIS TOWN
TO COME BACK TO A SENSE OF
NORMALITY AND HEALING.
>> AND TIME HEALS -- I GUESS IT
HEALS ALL WOUNDS MAYBE BUT THE
CHURCH IN SANDY HOOK AND ELEMENT
MEA
MEANT TREE SCHOOL IS THE LAST
PLACE THAT YOU EXPECT THIS TO
HAPPEN.
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN A TRAGEDY OF
THIS KIND, ESPECIALLY TO A
CHILD?
>> IT'S -- YOU LOSE YOUR SENSE
OF INNOCENCE.
YOU GO TO A SCHOOL THAT IS A
PLACE WHERE EVERYTHING IS SAFE
AND GOOD.
YOUR TEACHER IS A PERSON THAT
PROTECTS AND WE'RE HEARING
UNBELIEVABLE STORIES OF TEACHERS
AND ADMINISTRATORS LITERALLY
LAYING DOWN THEIR LIVES FOR
THEIR KIDS.
AT OUR CHURCH, IT WAS A SUNDAY
MORNING WORSHIP SERVICE.
LAST PLACE YOU'D EXPECT VIOLENCE
BUT VIOLENCE DID COME.
YOU HAVE TO TALK HONESTLY ABOUT
EVIL AND THAT GOOD OVERCOMES
EVIL AND I THINK YOU HAVE TO
MAKE SURE THAT YOUR KIDS FEEL
PROTECTED AND SAFE.
WE DID THAT AT OUR CHURCH.
IT'S A SAFE PLACE TO WORSHIP NOW
BUT WE'VE CREATED A SENSE OF
SAFETY AND PEOPLE NOW ARE
SMILING AGAIN AND I THINK YOU
JUST HAVE TO TALK HONESTLY WITH
YOUR CHILDREN AND LISTEN
HONESTLY AND GIVE HONEST ANSWERS
TO REALLY HARD QUESTIONS.
>> PASTOR, MY COLLEAGUE BACK IN
ATLANTA, DEBORAH FEYERICK HAS A
QUESTION FOR YOU.
>> PASTOR, IT'S INTERESTING.
I HEAR YOU SAY IT'S ABOUT GOOD
VERSUS EVIL BUT IT'S ALSO ABOUT
LIFE VERSUS DEATH AND I READ
SOMETHING THAT RESONATED WITH
ME.
A PSYCHOLOGIST WROTE, WE WALK
THROUGH LIFE WITH THE WONDERFUL
MYTH OF INVULNERABILITY.
WE THINK OUR HUMANITY IS
SOMETHING SPECIAL, SACRED, AND
PRECIOUS AND THEN SOMETHING LIKE
THIS COMES ALONG AND IT MAKES
YOU REALIZE THAT YOU ARE
FRAGILE, THAT YOU ARE VULNERABLE
AND THAT'S WHERE THE TRAUMA SETS
IN, THAT E. OH, MY GOD, THIS
COULD HAVE BEEN ANY OF OUR
SCHOOLS.
THIS COULD BE ANY OF OUR
CHILDREN AND, FRANKLY, THE
SHOOTER COULD HAVE BEEN SOMEBODY
WE ALL KNOW.
>> EXACTLY RIGHT.
I THINK THAT'S ONE OF THE ISSUES
THAT WE NEED TO TALK ABOUT AND
THIS IS WHAT WE'RE GOING TO TALK
ABOUT THIS WEEKEND.
IT MADE ME THINK ABOUT -- WE
NEED TO HAVE BETTER
CONVERSATIONS ABOUT HOW TO BE
BETTER PARENTS, HOW TO BE BETTER
FRIENDS, HOW TO ESTABLISH A
COMMUNITY WHERE WE CAN HAVE
REALLY HONEST CONVERSATIONS
ABOUT PEOPLE THAT HAVE MENTAL
ILLNESS AND I THINK THE CHURCH
IS A GOOD PLACE TO START THAT
CONVERSATION.
I THINK THE COMMUNITY AT LARGE
HAS TO COME TOGETHER AND WE HAVE
TO TALK ABOUT THE REALITIES OF
THE CULTURE IN WHICH WE LIVE.
WE DO NOT LIVE IN AN I'D LEGAL
LIST STICK BROKEN WORLD.
WE LIVE IN A BROKEN WORLD THAT
NEEDS REDEMPTION AND WE NEED TO
START HAVING SERIOUS
CONVERSATIONS ABOUT HOW TO BE
BETTER PARENTS, HOW TO BE BETTER
FRIENDS, HOW TO HAVE TOUGHER
CONVERSATIONS --
>> PASTOR, WITH THAT SAID, THEN,
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT HONEST
CONVERSATIONS AND BEING BETTER
PARENT.
I'M JUST GOING TO READ THIS.
THIS COMES ON THE HEEL -- THE
OREGON MALL SHOOTING, COLORADO
MOVIE THEATER WHICH I COVERED IN
DEPTH JUST A COUPLE OF MONTHS
AGO, CONGRESSWOMAN GABRIELLE
GIFFORDS.
AS A PASTOR, DO YOU THINK YOU
HAVE A RESPONSIBILITY TO TALK TO
YOUR CONGREGATION ABOUT GUN
CONTROL IN THIS COUNTRY?
>> YES.
BUT THE BIGGER QUESTION IS
VIOLENCE.
I AM CONCERNED ABOUT HOW EASY IT
IS FOR PEOPLE THAT ARE MEANT NT
DISTURBED TO GET GUNS.
I'M A GUN OWNER MYSELF BUT I
HAVE SERIOUS CONCERNS ABOUT HOW
EASY IT IS FOR PEOPLE TO GET
THEIR HANDS ON THE GUNS.
BUT HOW ABOUT THE CULTURE OF
VIOLENCE?
WHERE'S THE OUTRAGE --
>> PASTOR, HANG ON.
I DON'T WANT TO BE
DISRESPECTFUL.
YES, I AGREE WITH YOU BUT THIS
PARTICULAR ISSUE IS ABOUT GUNS.
THIS PERSON WENT IN WITH GUNS.
NUMEROUS GUNS AND KILLED MANY
PEOPLE, CHILDREN.
HE DIDN'T BEAT THEM UP.
HE DIDN'T KNIFE THEM.
HE DIDN'T SET OFF A CANISTER OR
A MOLITOFF COCKTAIL AND EVERY
TIME I'M ON A SCENE COVERING A
STORY LIKE THIS, THE PERSON DOES
IT WITH GUNS.
AND WE CONTINUE TO SAY IT'S
ABOUT A CULTURE OF VIOLENCE.
IT'S ABOUT THIS.
IT'S ABOUT GUNS, PASTOR.
>> FIRST OF ALL, I OWN GUNS AND
I'M NOT VIOLENT.
LISTEN, I'M WITH YOU.
I HEARD YOUR CONVERSATION
EARLIER AND I AGREE THAT WE NEED
TO HAVE CAREFUL EXAMINATION OF
WHO CAN PUT THEIR HANDS ON A
GUN.
BUT AT THE END OF THE DAY I KNOW
TONS OF PEOPLE WHO OWN GUNS WHO
ARE NOT VIOLENT.
I THINK WE NEED TO TALK ABOUT
BOTH.
I'M AGREEING WITH YOU, THAT
THERE IS A CULTURE OF VIOLENCE.
I DON'T THINK YOU CAN TALK ABOUT
ONE WITHOUT TALKING ABOUT THE
OTHER.
I AGREE WITH YOU.
WE HAVE TO TALK ABOUT BOTH.
>> YEAH.
AND I THINK THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO
ARE RESPECTFUL OF GUNS, WHO KNOW
HOW TO USE GUNS AND GET TRAINING
AND THEN PEOPLE WHO DON'T
RESPECT GUNS OR LIFE AND THAT'S
THE CONVERSATION WE NEED TO BE
HAVING.
>> NO BOUGHT ABOUT IT.
>> THANK YOU, PASTOR BOYD.
>> THANK YOU.
GOD'S PEACE ON THESE PEOPLE IN
CONNECTICUT.
>> AMEN.
THANK YOU.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA PROMISING TO
TAKE WHAT HE CALLS MEANINGFUL
ACTION TO PREVENT TRAGEDIES LIKE
THIS FROM HAPPENING AGAIN.
BRIANNA KEILAR IS LIVE WITH THE
LATEST FOR US.
THE PRESIDENT SAID MEANINGFUL
YESTERDAY.
HE EVEN TEARED UP.
I WAS AT THE WHITE HOUSE LAST
NIGHT FOR A -- SUPPOSED TO BE A
CELEBRATION BUT IT WAS KIND OF
SOMBER AND THE PRESIDENT
MENTIONED THAT AT THE CHRISTMAS
PARTY THE VICTIMS OF THIS
PARTICULAR TRAGEDY.
WHAT DOES HE MEAN BY MEANINGFUL?
>> Reporter: MEANINGFUL ACTION,
ACTUALLY, WE DON'T KNOW.
WHAT WE DO KNOW AND THIS IS THE
SENSE I'M GETTING IS THAT HE
DOES MEAN SOMETHING, THAT HE
DOES ACTUALLY MEAN THAT SOME
ACTION SHOULD BE TAKEN BUT IN
TERMS OF THE SPECIFICS, DON, WE
DON'T KNOW WHAT THEY ARE.
AND THIS IS THE SENSE I'M
GETTING THAT THIS IS A GENERAL
PROMISE TO PURSUE SOMETHING TO
TRY TO AVERT FUTURE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS ONE.
THE SENSE HERE AT THE WHITE
HOUSE IS THAT THE PRESIDENT HAS
SORT OF EXPERIENCED WITH THE
COUNTRY ALMOST A HANDFUL NOW OF
THESE TRAGEDIES BETWEEN FT.
HOOD, BETWEEN THE SHOOTING OF
CONGRESSWOMAN GABBY GIFFORDS,
THE SIKH TEMPLE SHOOTING THAT
YOU MENTIONED AND THIS ONE,
ESPECIALLY WITH THE AGE OF THE
VICTIMS, JUST SORT OF REALLY
BRINGING HOME THE FACT THAT
SOMETHING'S NOT WORKING.
THAT THERE ARE JUST TOO MANY OF
THESE INSTANCES HAPPENING AND
SOMETHING NEEDS TO BE DONE.
WE DON'T KNOW THE SPECIFICS.
TALKING TO PEOPLE WHO ARE
FAMILIAR WITH WHAT HIS OPTIONS
MAY BE, ONE OPTION MAY BE
FINDING A WAY TO LIMIT THE
NUMBER OF BULLETS AND MAGAZINES,
DEALING WITH MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES.
WE HAVE YET TO SEE WHAT ROLE
THAT PLAYED IN THIS TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT.
BUT REPORTING OF MENTAL HEALTH
IN A WAY THAT PEOPLE WHO
SHOULDN'T HAVE ACCESS TO GUNS
INDEED DON'T HAVE ACCESS TO
THEM.
THAT'S JUST INFORMED SPECULATION
AT THIS POINT, DON, AS WE TRY TO
FIGURE OUT WHAT THE PRESIDENT
MEANS WHEN HE SAYS SOMETHING
MEANINGFUL.
>> MEANINGFUL ACTION.
MEANINGFUL ACTION WOULD BE A
START, AT THE LEAST.
THANK YOU, BRIANNA KEILAR.
DEBORAH FEYERICK MONITORING
OTHER DEVELOPING NEWS FROM THE
CNN CENTER IN ATLANTA.
WHAT DO YOU HAVE?
>> OTHER THINGS HAPPENING AT
THIS HOUR, SECRETARY OF STATE
HILLARY CLINTON HAS SUSTAINED A
CONCUSSION AFTER FAINTING.
SHE'S BEEN MONITORED BY DOCTORS
AND IS NOW AT HOME.
>>> SYRIAN REBELS ARE MOSTLY IN
CONTROL OF ALEPPO.
THIS COMES WEEKS AFTER FIGHTING
WITH REGIME TROOPS AND IT'S A
SIGN THAT GOVERNMENT FORCES ARE
LOSING GROUND.
AT LEAST 250 GOVERNMENT SOLDIERS
HAD DEFECTED SIN THE INFANTRY
ACADEMY CAME UNDER SIEGE.
>>> AND IN THE UK, A MASS WAS
HELD TODAY FOR THE NURSE WHO
APPARENTLY HANGED HERSELF AFTER
A PRANK CALL.
HER HUSBAND AND CHILDREN SPOKE
ABOUT THEIR LOSS FOR THE FIRST
TIME SINCE HER DEATH.
SHE TOOK THE HOAX CALL FROM TWO
AUSTRALIAN DEEJAYS.
THE FUNERAL WILL BE HELD ON
MONDAY IN SOUTHERN INDIA.
DON?
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH, DEB.
WE'LL GET BACK TO YOU IN A
MINUTE.
YOU KNOW, THE CONNECTICUT
SHOOTING HAS CHILLED THE HEARTS
OF PEOPLE ALL ACROSS THIS
COUNTRY AND IT'S BROUGHT BACK
HORRIFYING MEMORIES OF THE
COLUMN BIN TRAGEDY.
FOR SURVIVORS IT'S LIKE RELIVING
THIS NIGHTMARE ALL OVER AGAIN.
IT'S ONE OF THE FIRST THINGS
THAT WE THINK ABOUT WHEN THEY
THINK ABOUT A SCHOOL SHOOTING.
JOINING ME NOW IS AN AUTHOR FROM
NEW YORK.
DAVE, YOU WROTE ABOUT THE
TRAGEDY.
DOES YESTERDAY'S KILLING BEAR A
RESEMBLANCE TO THAT OR VIRGINIA
TECH OR ANY OF THE OTHER
SHOOTINGS?
>> WELL, YES IT DOES IN A WHOLE
LOT OF WAYS.
ESPECIALLY EMOTIONALLY I THINK
FOR ALL OF US.
I TALKED TO QUITE A FEW OF THE
COLUMBINE SURVIVORS YESTERDAY
WHO WERE HAVING REALLY, REALLY
ROUGH DAYS IN DIFFERENT WAYS.
IT PULLS THAT TOGETHER AND THEN
OF COURSE THE SAME QUESTIONS
THAT WE'RE ASKING WITH EVERYONE
WANTING TO KNOW HE WHY AND WE
MADE A LOT OF MISTAKES IN THAT
CASE OF JUMPING TOO QUICKLY TO
WHY.
I THINK THE PRESS IS MUCH BETTER
NOW AT UNDERSTANDING TO BE MORE
CAUTIOUS ABOUT THESE THINGS BUT
STILL A DESIRE TO UNDERSTAND WHY
THIS HAPPENED AND HOW IT FITS
INTO THIS WIDER PICTURE OF WHY
ALL OF THESE SHOOTINGS.
>> IS THERE ANYTHING THAT --
WITH BETWEEN ALL OF THE
SHOOTINGS, THE SUSPECTS, IS
THERE ANYTHING THAT RESONATES
WITH YOU ABOUT DETECTING SIGNS
THAT A PERSON IS ABOUT TO COMMIT
SUCH A HORRIFIC CRIME OR DO
THESE PEOPLE SOMETIMES JUST
SNAP?
>> YEAH, THAT'S A GREAT
QUESTION.
THEY DEFINITELY DON'T SNAP.
THAT'S A WORD WE SHOULD ACTUALLY
TRY TO TAKE OUT OF OUR
VOCABULARY.
IN ALMOST ALL CASES IT'S A VERY
SLOW BUILD.
THE SECRET SERVICE DID A
REMARKABLE STUDY OF ALL OF THE
CASES OF SCHOOL SHOOTERS OVER A
25-YEAR PERIOD AND THE VAST
MAJORITY PLAN THEM IN ADVANCE.
MANY FOR WEEKS AND MONTHS IN
ADVANCE.
I BELIEVE I SAW BEFORE WE WENT
ON AIR THAT THERE'S A REPORT
THAT THIS GUNMAN TRIED TO BUY A
GUN ON TUESDAY OR EARLIER IN THE
WEEK.
SO AT LEAST EARLIER HE WAS
PLANNING.
THAT'S NORMAL.
IT'S TYPICALLY A SLOW D
DISINTEGRATION.
THERE ARE THREE MAIN TYPES AND
THE MOST PREVALENT PART IS THE
ANGRY SUPPRESSIVE.
PICTURE A PERSON WHO IS
SUICIDELY DEPRESSED, AND WRITING
ABOUT COMMITTING SUICIDE FOR TWO
YEARS.
IT'S A REALLY, REALLY SORT OF
SLOW, DOWNWARD SPIRAL.
PAST SADNESS INTO A SENSE OF
HOPELENESS AND SENSELENESS FOR
MOST OF THESE PEOPLE.
THAT MAY OR MAY NOT BE THE
SITUATION HERE BUT THAT'S MOST
OFTEN WHAT WE'RE LOOKING AT.
IF THERE'S A LESSON FROM ANY OF
THESE, THE MOST EASY WAY TO
IMPROVE THE SITUATION IS DEAL
WITH ADOLESCENT DEPRESSION.
>> I WAS JUST TALKING TO A WHITE
HOUSE CORRESPONDENT.
I WAS TALKING TO FORMER FBI
ASSISTANT DIRECTOR TOM FUENTES
ABOUT THIS.
THE PRESIDENT SAID SOME
MEANINGFUL ACTION TO MODIFY GUN
CONTROL.
HAVING WRITTEN ABOUT COLUMBINE,
WITNESSING VIRGINIA TECH AND
SOME OF THESE THINGS, WHAT DO
YOU THINK?
IS IT TIME TO DO SOMETHING
MEANFUL ABOUT GUN LAWS IN THIS
COUNTRY?
>> I THINK IT IS.
I THINK MOST OF US ARE FEELING
MORE HOPEFUL BECAUSE I THINK
WE'VE LEARNED THAT NO ONE OF
THESE EVENTS IS GOING TO CAUSE A
BIG CHANGE.
AFTER COLUMBINE THAT NOW THE
COUNTRY WILL WAKE UP AND WE'LL
DO SOMETHING AND IN FACT WE
DIDN'T.
WE LEFT THE ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN
HE CAN PYRE.
AFTER GABRIELLE GIFFORDS, THERE
WERE OTHER DIFFERENT TIMES.
I THINK WE'VE LEARNED OUR LESSON
THAT IT CAN'T BE A RESPONSE TO
ANY ONE TRAGEDY.
WE NEED TO MARSHAL FORCES AND
PEOPLE BECOMING MORE AND MORE
ADAMANT.
JUST LIKE YOU SAID EARLIER, WE
NEED TO BE MORE SERIOUS.
YOU SAID YOU'VE BEEN COVERING
THIS FOR YEARS AND EVERY TIME
YOU'RE ON SITE IT'S BECAUSE
SOMEONE DID THIS WITH A GUN.
LET'S FACE THE OBVIOUS, THAT
THERE ARE GUNS HERE.
IN CHINA, APPARENTLY THE SAME
DAY AS SOMEBODY WENT ON A
RAMPAGE WITH A KNIFE AND I DON'T
REMEMBER THE EXACT AMOUNT
INJURED, MORE THAN 20 PEOPLE.
AND SO FAR NONE OF THOSE PEOPLE
HAVE DIED BECAUSE IT'S VERY HARD
TO KILL OFF A LOT OF PEOPLE WITH
A KNIFE.
AND GUNS ARE HAVE THE PROBLEM.
WE HAVE A PROBLEM WITH THE
KILLERS THEMSELVES AND THE GUNS
AND WE NEED TO STOP THIS
CONVERSATION OF LIKE SHOULD WE
TALK ABOUT THE GUNS OR THE
KILLERS?
GUNS OR KILLERS?
IT'S BOTH.
WE NEED TO ADDRESS BOTH AND TRY
TO SHRINK BOTH OF THOSE AND MAKE
THE GUNS LESS AVAILABLE AND FIND
OUT WHAT LEADS TO KILLERS AND
THAT'S THE ONLY HOPE OF REDUCING
THIS DRAMATICALLY.
>> DAVE CULLEN, IT'S DEB
FEYERICK.
YOU SAW WHAT HAPPENED WITH
COLUMBINE.
YOU SAW HOW THAT PLAYED OUT.
THE QUESTION, OBVIOUSLY, IS WHEN
SOMEBODY WANTS TO DO SOMETHING
LIKE THIS, WHY DO YOU HAVE THOSE
WHO ARE IN FACT MOST VULNERABLE
TO GOING TO AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
TO 5, 6, 7, 8, 9-YEAR-OLDS,
THERE'S SOMETHING PATHOLOGICAL
ABOUT THAT.
>> IT IS.
IT WAS REALLY APPALLING TO ME.
I WENT BACK AND FORTH BETWEEN --
WELL, I'LL TELL YOU, I SPENT THE
LAST 13 YEARS TRYING TO
UNDERSTAND THE KILLERS AND
TRYING TO SORT OF PUT MYSELF IN
THEIR SHOES AND UNDERSTAND WHY.
BECAUSE I'VE BEEN WITH SO MANY
DIFFERENT CONFERENCES WITH, YOU
KNOW, PEOPLE WHO ARE AUTHORITIES
AND HAVE BEEN STUDYING THESE FOR
THEIR ENTIRE CAREER, SHRINKS,
LAW ENFORCEMENT, OTHER PEOPLE,
ONE THING THAT I'VE SETTLED ON
IS THAT THE KILLER ALWAYS HAS A
REASON.
IN THEIR MIND, IT'S NOT
SENSELESS REASON.
THERE WAS SOME REASONING THAT
WORKED FOR THEM AND IF WE'RE
GOING TO REALLY WANT TO SOLVE
THIS, WE HAVE TO GET IN THEIR
HEADS AND UNDERSTAND FROM THEIR
POINT OF VIEW.
SO THAT'S BEEN MY MISSION FOR
THE LAST SEVERAL YEARS BUT
YESTERDAY THAT WAS REALLY HARD
TO DO.
YOU JUST SHOWED THAT LITTLE BOY
GETTING INTERVIEWED AND I DON'T
KNOW HOW YOU SHOOT AT ONE -- I
DON'T KNOW HOW YOU KILL ANYBODY
BUT ESPECIALLY SOMEBODY LIKE
THAT, I DON'T KNOW HOW YOU DO
ONE.
I DON'T KNOW HOW YOU KEEP DOING
IT.
BUT ALL THAT ASIDE, I CAN TELL
YOU ACTUALLY HOW IT SOMETIMES
DOES HAPPEN AND WE DON'T KNOW IF
THIS IS THE SITUATION HERE BUT
MOST OFTEN WITH PEOPLE WHO ARE
DEEPLY DEPRESSED AND SUICIDAL,
THE MOST COMMON THING THEY DO IF
THEY ARE GOING TO DO SOMETHING
DRASTIC IS KILL THEMSELVES AND
THEN THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO IF GO
ONE STEP BEYOND THAT AND TAKE
OUT THE SOURCE OF THEIR PAIN
WHICH IS USUALLY BOSS,
GIRLFRIEND, A FAMILY MEMBER.
THEY SHOOT THE BOSS, GIRLFRIEND,
PARENT, WHOEVER IS SORT OF LIKE
THE SYMBOL OF THAT PAIN.
THE NEXT STEP OF PEOPLE WHO TAKE
IT ONE STEP FURTHER ARE PEOPLE
WHO ATTACK NOT JUST THAT PERSON
BUT OTHER PERSON AROUND THEM.
SO IF THE WIFE OR THE GIRLFRIEND
IS THE PROBLEM, YOU ALSO KILL
THE GIRLFRIEND WHO I KNOW IS
TALKING BAD BEHIND MY BACK.
>> DEB AND DAVE --
>> YES.
>> DEB AND DAVE, WE'VE TALKED A
LOT ABOUT THIS AND I THINK IT
HAS TO DO WITH SOMETHING THAT WE
DON'T DISCUSS A LOT AND THAT IS
THAT THING CALLED ATTACHMENT
INJURIES, WHEN PEOPLE FEEL
BETRAYED BY OTHER PEOPLE,
WHETHER IT'S RELEVANT IN THEIR
MIND OR NOT.
I'VE BEEN SPEAKING TO THERAPISTS
ABOUT THIS A LOT LATELY AND IT'S
SOMETHING WE'RE GOING TO LEARN
ABOUT.
PERHAPS IT'S WHAT HAPPENED IN
THIS CASE.
MAYBE NOT.
DAVE AND DEB, THANK YOU.
DEB, WE'LL GET BACK TO YOU IN
ATLANTA.
IN JUST TWO DAYS, STUDENTS HEAD
BACK TO SCHOOL.
WHAT CAN SCHOOLS DO IN THE WAKE
OF ALL OF THIS TO MAKE IT ALL
BETTER?
WHAT CAN THEY DO TO MAKE SURE
THAT THEIR STUDENTS FEEL SAFE
AND SAFEGUARD THE FACILITIES?
I'LL TALK TO AN EXPERT AHEAD.
From the best
players in history
to the number 1 club
in the world.
The potential of
Manchester United unlocked.
NYSE Euronext.
Unlocking the world's potential.
LOOK THIS ISN'T
MY FIRST CHRISTMAS.
THESE DEALS ALL SEEM GREAT
AT THE TIME...
BUT LATER...
[ shirt ]
MERRY CHRISTMAS, EVERYBODY!
NOT SO MUCH.
HO HO HO!
THIS ISN'T
THAT KIND OF DEAL.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SAVE ON GROUND SHIPPING
AT FEDEX OFFICE.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYONE.
I'M STANDING BY THE NEWTOWN
METHODIST CHURCH AND IT'S OPEN
24 HOURS FOR ANYONE WHO WANTS TO
GRIEF VE OR PAY THEIR RESPECTS
ANYONE WHO DIED.
THIS HAD IS A VERY BUSY SQUARE
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
SOME PEOPLE ARE COMING FROM
TOWNS AROUND THE AREA JUST TO
SEE WHAT'S GOING ON HERE AND TO
HELP CONSOLE SOME OF THE FOLKS
HERE.
AS I SAID AT THE BEGINNING OF
THIS BROADCAST, WE'RE GOING TO
GO THROUGH THIS AS SENSITIVELY
AND RESPECTFUL AS WE CAN DO.
THIS IS TOUGH FOR ANY JOURNALIST
TO COVER BUT NOT AS NEAR AS
DIFFICULT AS WHAT THE FAMILIES
ARE DEALING WITH AND OUR HEARTS
AND PRAYERS GO OUT WITH THEM.
AND THAT SAID, I WANT TO SAY
THAT WE ARE AWAITING THE NEWEST
NEWS CONFERENCE FROM THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW RIGHT NOW.
LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIAL SAYS --
AND THIS IS THE SUSPECT'S NAME.
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA.
WE WILL SAY THAT AS LITTLE AS
POSSIBLE.
WE HAVE TO DO IT FOR THE RECORD.
THAT HE HAD SOME SORT OF
ALTERCATION WITH PEOPLE AT THE
SCHOOL A FEW DAYS BEFORE THE
SHOOTING.
THE OFFICIAL DOES NOT KNOW --
DOESN'T KNOW ANY DETAILS ABOUT
THAT ALTERCATION OR WHO IT
INVOLVED.
WE ALSO LEARNED FROM A LAW
ENFORCEMENT SOURCE THAT THE
SUSPECT TRIED TO BUY A GUN THREE
DAYS BEFORE THE SHOOTING BUT
DIDN'T HAVE THE PROPER
PAPERWORK.
AND POLICE ALSO REVEAL TODAY
THAT THREE GUNS, NOT TWO AS
PREVIOUSLY THOUGHT, WERE FOUND
NEAR THE SUSPECT'S BODY INSIDE
THE SCHOOL.
THE VICTIM'S BODIES HAVE BEEN
REMOVED FROM THE SCHOOL.
I SHOULD SAY, THE HEROES IN ALL
OF THIS.
THEIR BODIES HAVE BEEN REMOVED
FROM THE SCHOOL.
AND THEY HAVE BEEN TAKEN TO THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER'S OFFICE.
THEIR NAMES ARE EXPECTED TO BE
RELEASED SOON.
THOSE ARE PEOPLE WHO LED
EXTRAORDINARY LIVES AND WERE
TAKEN AWAY WAY TOO SOON.
AND JUST THIS MORNING, PARENTS
WERE DROPPING OFF THEIR KIDS
LIKE ANY OTHER DAY.
JUST YESTERDAY MORNING, I SHOULD
SAY.
LIKE ANY OTHER DAY.
NO ONE COULD HAVE MANAGED THE
CARNAGE AND HORROR THAT WOULD
OCCUR JUST HOURS LATER.
SO MANY OF THE VICTIMS, SADLY,
INNOCENT CHILDREN.
HOW DO YOU COPE, EVEN BEGIN TO
HEAL OR EXPLAIN WHAT HAS
HAPPENED HERE?
I DON'T KNOW WHERE YOU START,
WHICH IS WHY I WANT THE HELP OF
A CLINICAL PSYCHOLOGIST.
JEFF GARDERE IS HERE.
JEFF, I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHERE TO
BEGIN WITH THIS.
WITH THE COMMUNITY DEALING WITH
26 PEOPLE, WITH 20 CHILDREN,
WITH FAMILIES DEALING WITH THIS,
PARENTS WHO SENT THEIR KIDS TO
SCHOOL, WENT OFF TO WORK OR OFF
TO DO WHATEVER THEY WERE DOING,
GETTING READY FOR THE HOLIDAYS,
MAYBE THEY WERE WELL, I JUST THO
BE VERY HONEST WITH OURSELVES
THAT MANY OF US FEEL LIKE YOU,
DON.
WE DON'T KNOW WHERE TO BEGIN.
BUT THERE IS A PLACE AND THAT IS
WHAT THE POLICE ARE DOING AND
THE MOBILE CRISIS UNITS ARE
DOING NOW WHICH IS PROVIDING
DEBRIEFING TO NOT JUST GET
INFORMATION BUT TO ALLOW THESE
FAMILIES TO ALLOW THE PARENTS,
TO ALLOWS THE FRIENDS TO JUST BE
ABLE TO TALK ABOUT WHAT THEY'RE
EXPERIENCING.
ALLOWING THEM TO EASE INTO THIS
GRIEVING PROCESS THAT'S GOING TO
BE TAKING SUCH A LONG TIME FOR
THEM TO GET THROUGH, BUT MOST
IMPORTANTLY, TO HELP STABILIZE
THEM, MAKING SURE THAT THEY GET
INFORMATION THAT THEY GET FOOD,
THAT THEY GET WARMTH, THAT THEY
GET SUPPORT AND THAT THEY HAVE
AN OPEN COMMUNICATION, SHOULDERS
THAT ARE AVAILABLE FOR THEM TO
CRY ON TO LEAN ON.
THAT'S WHERE YOU BEGIN.
>> PEOPLE HAVE BEEN TALKING
ABOUT THIS SUSPECT, THIS
SHOOTER, THE GUNMAN, THAT HE HAD
A FORM OF AUTISM.
AUTISM IS NOT A MENTAL ILLNESS.
IT'S NOT A SOCIAL ILLNESS.
IT'S A NEUROLOGICAL DISORDER,
RIGHT?
>> THAT IS CORRECT.
>> NEUROBIOLOGICAL DISORDER.
>> YES, BIOLOGICAL.
WHEN WE'RE LOOKING AT AUTISM,
WE'RE LOOKING AT, THERE IS A
HIGH INHERITABILITY, IN OTHER
WORDS THAT IT IS INHERITED.
AND QUITE OFTEN THERE ARE ISSUES
WITH THE CHROMOSOMES, 15 AND 16
WHICH ARE MARKERS FOR AUTISM.
SO WE SEE IT IS AS YOU SAY THIS
BIOLOGICAL COMPONENT.
WE FIND THAT 85% OF PEOPLE WITH
AUTISM ARE MENTALLY RETARDED BUT
YOU DO HAVE A CERTAIN PORTION
WHO ARE PART OF THE AUTISM
SPECTRUM AND HAVE AS THIS PERSON
REPORTEDLY ALLEGEDLY HAD, SOME
SORT OF ASPERGER'S WHICH IS A
VERY HIGH FUNCTIONING AUTISM AND
SOME OF THOSE INDIVIDUALS ARE
EXTREMELY INTELLIGENT, BUT HAVE
PROBLEMS LIKE OTHER AUTISTIC
PERSONS BEING ABLE TO INTERACT
IN A SOCIAL WAY, SPENDING A LOT
OF TIME ALONE JUST NOT HAVING
THE GENERAL SOCIAL SKILLS.
>> BUT YOU KNOW WHAT, I DON'T
WANT TO DISFARNLG EVERYONE WHO
HAS AUTISM.
YOU DON'T WANT TO BLAME AUTISM
FOR THEIR PROBLEM.
MANY PEOPLE AS I'M READING HERE
DESCRIBE THIS GUNMAN AS NICE AND
POLITE.
THEY SAY THEY WERE SHOCKED
BECAUSE HE NEVER SHOWED ANY
VIOLENT TENDENCIES.
I MEAN, CAN YOU -- DOES AUTISM
EXPLAIN THIS TYPE OF BEHAVIOR?
I DON'T THINK SO.
>> QUITE FRANKLY, AUTISM DOESN'T
EXPLAIN THIS AT ALL.
I WORK WITH MANY AUTISTIC
PATIENTS.
I'VE WORKED WITH PEOPLE WHO HAVE
HIGH FUNCTIONING AUTISM, WHICH
IS ASPERGER'S, AND BY THE WAY, I
SHOULD POINT OUT AS A CAUTIONARY
TALE, WE FIND ONE OF THE MAJOR
CAUSES OF AUTISM IS THIS WHOLE
IDEA OF NOT ONLY IS IT PASSED
ON, BUT CERTAINLY SOME IMMUNE
PROBLEMS THAT WOMEN HAVE WHEN
THEY'RE CARRYING THEIR CHILDREN.
AS FAR AS IN UTERO.
BUT YES, WE JUST DO NOT FIND
THAT PEOPLE WHO ARE YOU ANT --
AUTISTIC.
WE DO FIND THERE IS AN ISSUE AS
A MAN GOES INTO MANHOOD OR ADULT
HOOD, THEY MAY BE MUCH HARDER TO
MANAGE, THEY MAY HAVE SOME FITS
OF ANGER, BUT WE DON'T SEE THEM
GOING OUT AND COMMITTING MURDER
AND MAYHEM.
THIS IS MORE OF AN ISSUE BETWEEN
A PARENT AND A CHILD GETTING
THEM TO JUST BE MORE PRODUCTIVE.
ESPECIALLY WHEN WE'RE LOOKING AT
ASPERGER'S, WE THINK THAT THERE
ARE HEADS OF CORPORATIONS WHO
HAVE ASPERGER'S, AGAINST THIS IS
HIGH FUNCTIONING AUTISM.
>> AND IT'S INTERESTING, IT
ALWAYS SEEMS TO BE SOME PERSON
IN THEIR 20s, SOME YOUNG PERSON
AND YOU KNOW, GETTING OLDER YOU
REALIZE WHEN I WAS IN MY 20s, I
THOUGHT I KNEW EVERYTHING AND
EVERYTHING WOULD SET ME OFF.
THE OLDER YOU GET, THE MORE YOU
REALIZE THAT YOU DON'T KNOW.
IS THERE SOMETHING JUST ABOUT
YOUTH THAT WE'RE NOT TEACHING
OUR KIDS OR YOUNG PEOPLE THAT
THEY THINK THEY KNOW EVERYTHING
AND THEY THINK THAT YOU KNOW,
THE WORLD REVOLVES AROUND THEM
AND THEY HAVE THE RIGHT AND THE
POWER TO TAKE OUT OTHER PEOPLE?
>> WELL, IT IS THAT, DON.
WE SEE THAT OUR YOUTH ARE VERY
MUCH DISAFFECTED, AND PART OF
THAT, AND YOU KNOW, YOU'VE KNOWN
ME FOR YEARS NOW.
I'M NOT INTO THE POINTING
FINGERS AND BLAMING THE MEDIA
AND BLAMING THIS OR THAT.
THOUGH WE DO HAVE TO LOOK AT
THIS WHOLE IDEA OF MENTAL HEALTH
LAWS, GUN LAWS AND PERHAPS
HELPING PEOPLE MORE THAN THEY'RE
GETTING HELP.
BUT I REALLY DO BELIEVE THAT TOO
OFTEN, OUR CHILDREN LIVE IN A
VIRTUAL REALITY.
THE REALITY OF MANY VIOLENT
VIDEOS.
EVEN THOUGH WE HAVE A LOT OF
KIDS WHO PLAY THESE VIOLENT
VIDEOS AND NOTHING HAPPENS TO
THEM, THEY DON'T GO OUT AND KILL
ANYONE, IF YOU HAVE A PERSON WHO
HAS SOME MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES OR
WHO MAY BE LIMITED IN SOME WAY
OR IS IN AN ENVIRONMENT THAT IS
CATASTROPHIC, WE HAVE TO BE
CAREFUL TO NOT LET THEM DRIFT
INTO THE MARGINS OF SOCIETY AND
IN THIS CASE AS WE NOTE WITH
THIS YOUNG MAN, SPENDING A LOT
OF TIME GAMING, SPENDING A LOT
OF TIME ON THESE VIDEO GAMES
BECAUSE THAT, AS WE SEE, IS A
RECIPE FOR DISASTER.
>> LIVING VIRTUAL LIVES INSTEAD
OF INTERACTING AND LIVING A
REAL-LIFE WITH OTHER PEOPLE.
THANK YOU, JEFF, GARDERE.
APPRECIATE THAT.
>> SURE.
>> YOU CAN BET THAT SCHOOLS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY ARE GOING TO
BE RE-EVALUATING THEIR SECURITY
PROCEDURES.
THIS SCHOOL DISTRICT HAD JUST
DONE IT TO TRY TO PREVENT A
TRAGEDY SIMILAR TO WHAT HAPPENED
HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
KENNETH TRUMP IS THE PRESIDENT
OF THE NATIONAL SECURITY AND
SAFETY SERVICES.
HE JOINS ME LIVE FROM CLEVELAND.
PARENTS ARE ON THE EDGE THINKING
ABOUT SENDING THEIR CHILDREN
BACK TO SCHOOL AFTER THE
SHOOTING.
I IMAGINE MANY PARENTS ARE.
WHAT CAN SCHOOLS IMMEDIATELY DO
TO KEEP THEIR KIDS SAFE?
>> PARENTS NEED TO REMEMBER THAT
THE FIRST THING THEY SHOULD DO
IS TO SEND THEIR CHILDREN TO
SCHOOL.
MONDAY WILL BE THE SAFEST DAY
YOU COULD EVER BE IN A SCHOOL IN
THIS COUNTRY BECAUSE THERE'S
GOING TO BE A HEIGHTENED
AWARENESS AND HEIGHTENED
SECURITY MEASURES.
THAT'S CRITICAL.
WE SAW WAVES OF CHILDREN STAY
HOME AFTER COLUMN BRIAN.
WE DON'T WANT TO SEE THAT NOW.
PARENTS SHOULD FEEL COMFORTABLE
TALKING TO YOUR PRINCIPALS.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING IN MY CHILD'S
SCHOOL TO IMPROVE SAFETY?
HOW WELL PREPARED ARE YOU TO
MANAGE AN EMERGENCY SITUATION?
TESTIMONY SCHOOLS ARE ALREADY
DOING THINGS.
PARENTS, UNFORTUNATELY, JUST
DON'T KNOW ABOUT IT OR HAVEN'T
ASKED AND THE SCHOOLS PERHAPS
HAVEN'T COMMUNICATED AS PRO
ACTIVELY AS THEY SHOULD.
I DON'T THINK WE NEED TO THROW
OUT THE PLAYBOOK OF BEST
PRACTICES IN SCHOOL SAFETY.
WE DON'T NEED TO BE TEACHING
ELEMENTARY KIDS TO THROW PENCILS
AND BACKPACKS AT ARMED INTRUDERS
AND HAVE A METAL DETECTOR AT
EVERY DOOR.
WE NEED TO FOCUS ON THE
FUNDAMENTALS THAT WE'VE LEARNED
FROM COLUMBINE DEALING WITH
PREVENTION, MENTAL HEALTH
SERVICES, COUNSELORS,
PSYCHOLOGISTS, SECURITY, SCHOOL
RESOURCE OFFICERS, TRAINING YOUR
STAFF, HAVING EMERGENCY PLANS,
PRACTICING DRILLS.
THESE THINGS ARE SOLID BEST
PRACTICES.
>> HEY, KENNETH, I WANT TO GO
BACK TO SOMETHING YOU SAID.
EVERY SINGLE PERSON TO A PERSON,
EVERYONE WHO'S SPOKEN TO ME
TODAY ABOUT THIS ISSUE TALKING
ABOUT GUNS, EVERYONE HAS SAID
MENTAL HEALTH.
THAT SEEMS TO BE A BIG ISSUE.
IS THERE SOMETHING THAT WE'RE
MISSING WHEN IT COMES TO MENTAL
HEALTH OR TEACHING PEOPLE ABOUT
MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES OR LEARNING
MORE ABOUT MENTAL HEALTH OF
SNUNLDS IS THERE SOMETHING
MISSING HERE?
>> WELL, IF YOU RECALL BACK TO
COLUMBINE, FOR YEARS, BULLYING
WAS BLAMED, BUT IN SOME RESEARCH
THAT WAS DONE BY TWO SEPARATE
AUTHORS, THEY REALLY CAME DOWN
TO THE SAME ISSUE AGAIN OF
MENTAL HEALTH.
I THINK IT'S VERY EASY TO TALK
ABOUT GETTING YOUR ARMS AROUND
BULLYING OR THINGS THAT WE CAN
ALL RELATE TO, BUT MENTAL HEALTH
IS MUCH MORE COMPLEX.
THERE ARE MANY PEOPLE WALKING
OUR STREETS WITH UNDIAGNOSED AND
OR UNTREATED MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES.
HOW DO WE KNOW THAT?
IT'S EASIER TO PREDICT STUDENT
ON STUDENT VIOLENCE AND TO GET A
JUMP AHEAD OF THAT WHEN YOU KNOW
YOUR KIDS.
IT'S HARDER FOR A PRINCIPAL TO
KNOW A LONE WOLF ACTOR IS GOING
TO WALK ACROSS THE SCHOOLHOUSE
DOOR AND WHAT THEIR MENTAL
STATUS IS.
>> YEAH.
LISTEN, LET'S TALK MORE ABOUT
JUST SECURING THE SCHOOLS.
WE CAN'T TURN SCHOOLS INTO MINI
PRISONS FOR STUDENTS.
SO THEN WHAT DO YOU DO?
>> THE FIRST AND BEST LINE OF
DEFENSE IS ALWAYS A WELL-TRAINED
HIGHLY ALERT STAFF AND STUDENT
BODY.
THE NUMBER ONE WAY WE FIND OUT
ABOUT WEAPONS IN SCHOOL
CONSISTENTLY HAS BEEN FROM KIDS
WHO KNOW THAT OTHER KIDS HAVE
THEM AND WHEN WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT VIOLENCE INSIDE THE
SCHOOL, HAVING SCHOOL RESOURCE
OFFICERS WHO BUILD RELATIONSHIPS
WITH KIDS ALONG WITH OTHER
SCHOOL STAFF SO THAT THE KIDS
COME FORWARD TO TELL YOU
PROBLEMS THAT ARE GOING ON AT
HOME.
ABUSE, FAMILY DYSFUNCTIONAL
ISSUES, SITUATIONS THAT ARE
GOING TO ADD FAMILY STRESSORS
THAT MAY SPILL OVER INTO THE
SCHOOL.
TALKING WITH YOUR F