BASKETBALL.
ONE OF THE YOUNG VICTIMS PLAYED
FOR HIS TEAM.
>> NEVER EXPECTED IT.
SHOCKED.
>> THAT SHOCK IS STILL EVIDENT
EVERYWHERE YOU LOOK.
26 CHRISTMAS TREES LINE THE CURB
ACROSS THE STREET FROM THE
FIREHOUSE WHERE SOME OF THE
CHILDREN FLED THE GUNFIRE.
THIS MORNING MOVING VANS DROVE
PASS, DOWN THE ROAD TO SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY, TO START THE
PROCESS OF RESETTLING THE
STUDENTS AT A NEW SCHOOL.
20 LITTLE FLAGS DOT THE CURB
JUST OUTSIDE THE NEWTOWN HIGH
SCHOOL.
TEDDY BEARS AT RAM'S PASTURE.
ANGELS KEEPING WATCH NEAR THE
CENTER OF TOWN.
AND THE TOWN'S FLAG IN THE
CENTER OF MAIN STREET AT
HALF-STAFF.
AND THE ONCE JOYFUL CHRISTMAS
TREE NOW HAS A DIFFERENT GLOW.
SURROUNDED BY MEMORIAL CANDLES
AND THE LIGHTS OF THE WORLD'S
MEDIA.
THE RESIDENTS OF NEWTOWN KNOW IT
WILL TAKE TIME FOR THIS TOWN TO
HEAL.
BUT THEY'RE ALSO DETERMINED TO
KNOW THE WORLD THAT NEWTOWN WILL
NOT JUST BECOME ANOTHER WORD FOR
TRAGEDY.
>> THE TOWN RIGHT NOW IS
MOURNING.
WE'RE SAD.
I THINK -- I THINK DOWN THE
ROAD, WE'LL DEFINITELY BE
STRONGER.
YOU KNOW WE HAVE TO BE STRONGER.
>>> GOOD EVENING, EVERYONE.
WE ARE LIVE ONCE AGAIN TONIGHT
FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, A
COMMUNITY STRUGGLING WITH GRIEF,
REACHING OUT TO ONE ANOTHER FOR
COMFORT, BEGINNING THE LONG,
LONG PROCESS OF SAYING GOODBYE
TO SO MANY YOUNG LIVES CUT FAR
TOO SHORT.
MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS WE MIND THE
PEOPLE OF THIS COMMUNITY THAT
THEY'RE NOT ALONE IN THEIR
GRIEF.
PEOPLE STOP BY TO LEAVE CANDLES
AND FLOWERS, TEDDY BEARS, NOTES
OF COMFORT.
IT'S A DAUNTING CONCEPT, THE
IDEA OF TRYING SOMEHOW TO MOVE
ON WITHOUT THE 20 SIX AND 7-YEAR
OLDS.
TRYING TO MOVE ON WITHOUT THE
ADULTS THAT WERE ALSO KILLED AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
MOVING ON MAY NOT BE POSSIBLE
FOR OOLONG TIME, IF EVER.
IT'S NOT CLEAR WHEN THE STUDENTS
IN SANDY HOOK WILL RETURN TO
CLASS, BUT WHEN THEY DO, IT WILL
BE IN A DIFFERENT BUILDING, IN A
DIFFERENT SCHOOL IN A
NEIGHBORING TOWN.
EVERYTHING IS DIFFERENT NOW.
EVERYTHINGMENT.
FOR THE FAMILIES HERE, THIS WEEK
IS ABOUT TRYING TO FIND A WAY TO
SAY GOODBYE, AND TO HONOR THE
LIVES OF THEIR CHILDREN, THE
LIVES OF THEIR TEACHERS AND
SCHOOL ADMINISTRATORS.
THERE ARE THREE FUNERALS
SCHEDULED FOR THE REST OF THE
WEEK FOR THREE 6-YEAR-OLDS, AND
THERE WERE TWO FUNERALS TODAY,
ALSO FOR 6-YEAR-OLDS, FOR JACK
PINTO AND NOAH POZNER.
TONIGHT WE REMEMBER JACK AND
NOAH, AND WE WISH THEIR FAMILIES
AND THEIR FRIENDS AND THEIR
CLASSMATES A MODICUM OF PEACE
AND LOTS OF STRENGTH AT THIS
UNIMAGINABLY DIFFICULT TIME.
IN A TRIBUTE TO THE LITTLE BOY
WHO LOVES SPORTS, TEAMMATES FROM
THE LOCAL YOUTH WRESTLING
ASSOCIATION WORE THEIR UNIFORMS
AND MEDALS TO 6-YEAR-OLD JACK
PINTO'S FUNERAL.
JACK WAS AN AVID SPORTS FAN, NOT
JUST WRESTLING, BUT BASEBALL,
BASKETBALL, AND SKIING.
HIS FIRST LOVE, HOWEVER, WAS
FOOTBALL.
HE IDOLIZED THE NEW YORK GIANTS'
VICTOR CRUZ, WHO PAID TRIBUTE TO
HIS LITTLE FAN BY WRITING HIS
NAME ON HIS CLEATS BEFORE A GAME
THIS PAST WEEKEND.
ACCORDING TO "THE NEW YORK
TIMES," A FAMILY FRIEND WHO GAVE
A EULOGY AT THE FUNERAL
DESCRIBED JACK AS THE KIND OF
BOY WHO COMMANDED ALL THE
ATTENTION IN THE ROOM, AND THAT
HE WANTED NOTHING MORE THAN TO
CATCH UP WITH HIS OLDER BEN,
WHOM HE WOULD HAVE FOLLOWED
ANYWHERE.
IN HIS OBITUARY, JACK'S FAMILY
WROTE, "IN LIFE AND IN DEATH,
JACK WILL FOREVER BE REMEMBERED
FOR THE IMMEASURABLE JOY HE
BROUGHT TO ALL WHO HAD THE
PLEASURE OF KNOWING HIM, A JOY
WHOSE WIDE REACH BELIED HIS SIX
SHORT YEARS."
ALSO LAID TO REST TODAY, NOAH
POZNER, WHO JUST CELEBRATED HIS
SIXTH BIRTHDAY LAST MONTH WITH
HIS TWIN AND BEST FRIEND,
AVIELLE.
THEY WERE BOTH AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
ON FRIDAY SHE APPARENTLY HID IN
A BATHROOM DURING THE ATTACK.
SHE SURVIVED.
NOAH DID NOT.
>> WE ARE ALL COMPLETELY
SHATTERED.
IT'S BEEN A VERY, VERY ROUGH FEW
DAYS.
NOBODY IS GETTING MUCH SLEEP.
YOU KNOW, WE'RE HOLDING TOGETHER
AS BEST WE CAN.
BUT YOU NEVER, EVER THINK THAT
SOMETHING LIKE THIS COULD HAPPEN
TO YOUR FAMILY.
>> NOAH'S AUNT SAYS HE LOVED TO
READ AND LOVED TO FIGURE OUT HOW
THINGS WORKED.
SHE SAID HE WAS EXTREMELY
LIVELY, THE LIGHT OF THE ROOM.
SHE'LL REMEMBER HIS BIG BLUE
EYES, A BOY WITH A BIG HEART WHO
LOVED HIS PARENTS, HIS OLDER
SISTERS AND BROTHER, AND HIS
TWIN MOST OF ALL.
>> THEY DON'T KNOW THE WAY IN
WHICH NOAH PASSED AWAY, BUT
OBVIOUSLY THEY WERE THERE DURING
THE WHOLE EVENT, AND WERE LED
OUT.
AND IT'S NOT -- SHE JUST TURNED
6.
ARIEL JUST TURNED 6.
AND HER OLDER SISTER IS 8.
HOW DO YOU TELL THEM THEIR
BROTHER DIED?
IT'S THE UNTHINKABLE, REALLY.
>> IN HIS OBITUARY, HIS FAMILY
SAID HE WAS IMPISH AND LARGER
THAN LIFE.
THEY CALLED HIM A LITTLE SOUL
DEVOID OF SPITE AND MEANNESS.
THEY WROTE EVERYTHING HE DID
CONVEYED ACTION AND ENERGY
THROUGH LOVE.
HE WAS THE LIGHT OF OUR FAMILY.
HE WILL BE FOREVER MISSED.
>> WE'VE JUST SEEN THE EULOGY
DELIVERED BY HIS MOTHER.
IT WAS PUBLISHED BY "THE NEW
YORK TIMES" AND DISTRIBUTED BY
THE PRESS.
I WANT TO READ PART OF IT TO
YOU.
YOU WERE A LITTLE BOY WHOSE LIFE
FORCE HAD THE GRAVITATIONAL PULL
OF A CELESTIAL BODY.
YOU WERE LIGHT AND LOVE,
MISCHIEF AND PRANKS.
YOU ADORED YOUR FAMILY WITH
EVERY FIBER OF YOUR 6-YEAR-OLD
BEING.
WE ARE ALL OF US ELEVATED IN OUR
HUMANITY BY HAVING KNOWN YOU.
A LITTLE MAVERICK WHO DIDN'T
ALWAYS WANT TO DO HIS SCHOOL
WORK OR CLEAN UP HIS TOYS WHEN
PRACTICING HIS NINJA MOVES OR
SUPER MARIO ON THE Wii SEEMED
FAR MORE IMPORTANT.
NOAH, YOU WILL NOT PASS THROUGH
THIS WAY AGAIN.
I CAN ONLY BELIEVE THAT YOU WERE
PLANTED ON EARTH TO BLOOM IN
HEAVEN.
TAKE FLIGHT, MY BOY, SOAR.
THE WORDS OF A MOTHER GRIEVING
FOR HER LOST SON.
ONE THING THAT WE'VE BEEN DOING
HERE IS REALLY TRYING TO KEEP
OUR FOCUS ON THE LIVES LOST.
AND THE LIVES OF THE PEOPLE HERE
WHO DIED LED, THE HEROS WHO
SAVED LIVES, WHO STOPPED EVEN
MORE BLOODSHED, AND OFTEN PUT
THEMSELVES IN HARM'S WAY TO DO
IT.
THE TEACHERS AND THE SCHOOL
ADMINISTRATORS.
WE'VE AVOIDED FOCUSING ON THE
KILLER, BECAUSE HE IS GONE, AND
FRANKLY, WE DON'T WANT HIM TO BE
REMEMBERED.
CERTAINLY NOT HIS NAME.
WE TRIED TO BE CAREFUL AND
RESPECTFUL OF WHAT THE FAMILIES
HERE ARE DOING THROUGH, AND WE
WILL CONTINUE TO DO THAT.
WE TRIED NOT TO INTRUDE ON THEIR
SUFFERING.
AFTER LAST NIGHT'S PROGRAM WE
GOT A CALL FROM THE McDONNELL
FAMILY.
THEIR 7-YEAR-OLD GRACE, AMAZING
GRACE, DIED ON FRIDAY.
I SPOKE WITH GRACE'S PARENTS AT
LENGTH TODAY, AND WE'RE GOING TO
BRING YOU THAT INTERVIEW
TOMORROW.
WE WERE GOING TO BRING TO IT YOU
TONIGHT, BUT WE HAD A TECHNICAL
PROBLEM WITH IT.
WE WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT WE DO
IT RIGHT, AND WE BRING YOU THE
COMPLETE INTERVIEW.
SO WE'LL DO THAT -- WE'LL BRING
THAT TO YOU TOMORROW.
TONIGHT WE REMEMBER ALL THE
VICTIMS, AND ALSO THE HEROES OF
THIS TRAGEDY, THE TEACHERS WHO
DID SO MUCH TO PROTECT THEIR
STUDENTS AND THE FIRST
RESPONDERS.
HERE IS WHAT LIEUTENANT VANCE OF
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
SAID ABOUT THOSE FIRST
RESPONDERS.
>> THE FACULTY, STAFF IN THAT
SCHOOL DID EVERYTHING THAT THEY
POSSIBLY COULD TO PROTECT THOSE
CHILDREN.
I CAN TELL YOU THAT THE FIRST
RESPONDERS THAT GOT TO THAT
SCENE WHEN THE ACTIVE TEAM THAT
ENTERED THE SCHOOL SAVED MANY
LIVES.
I CAN TELL YOU IT BROKE OUR
HEARTS WE COULDN'T SAVE THEM
ALL.
>> WELL, LAST NIGHT'S MEMORIAL,
THE FIRST RESPONDERS GOT A
STANDING OVATION FROM A VERY
GRATEFUL COMMUNITY.
[ APPLAUSE ]
ROB MANNA AND RAY KORBO ARE
FIREFIGHTERS.
HOW YOU BOTH HOLDING UP?
>> DIFFICULT EVERY DAY.
EVERY DAY IT'S A LITTLE BIT
BETTER.
BUT IT'S A CHALLENGE.
IT'S CERTAINLY A CHALLENGE.
>> ONE OF THE THINGS I KNOW YOU
GUYS HAVE BEEN DOING IS HANDING
OUT GIFTS TO LITTLE KIDS, THINGS
FROM THE RED CROSS.
THAT'S GOT TO BRING SOME
COMFORT.
>> DEFINITELY HELPS.
OVERWHELMING AMOUNT OF STUFFED
ANIMALS AND TEDDY BEARS CAME
STREAMING INTO THE FIREHOUSE.
AND WE'RE DOING WHAT WE CAN TO
GIVE IT OUT TO THE CHILDREN IN
TOWN.
>> YOU WERE BORN HERE, RIGHT?
>> YES.
>> YOU'RE FROM HERE ORIGINALLY.
TELL PEOPLE ABOUT THIS
COMMUNITY.
I MEAN, I'VE JUST BEEN STRUCK
ABOUT HOW CLOSE-KNIT IT SEEMS.
AND PROBABLY NOW MORE THAN EVER.
>> YEAH, THE OUTPOURING OF
SUPPORT FROM PEOPLE IN THE
COMMUNITY AND THE UNITY AND, YOU
KNOW, THE EMOTION IS
OVERWHELMING.
I CAN'T SAY ENOUGH OF THE
SUPPORT WE'VE BEEN GETTING FROM
EVEN OUTSIDE, OTHER COMMUNITIES,
AND, YOU KNOW, ALL AROUND THE
COUNTRY.
THE PHONE IS RINGING OFF THE
HOOK FOR PEOPLE WHO WANT TO
BRING FOOD AND SUPPLIES OR
WHATEVER THEY CAN.
>> I KNOW ON THAT HORRIBLE DAY
ON FRIDAY, YOU GUYS WERE
ASSIGNED TO A TRIAGE AREA.
AND IT DIDN'T UNFORTUNATELY END
UP BEING USED.
THAT MUST HAVE BEEN A -- JUST A
SICKENING FEELING, TO BE THERE
AT THIS TRIAGE UNIT AND REALIZE
THERE IS NOT PEOPLE COMING IN.
>> AT THE TIME, A FEW TIMES
DURING THE INCIDENT, I ACTUALLY
THOUGHT TO MYSELF SHOULD I BE
HOPING THAT THIS AREA WAS FILLED
WITH INJURED PEOPLE?
>> RIGHT.
>> I WAS ALMOST WISHING THAT --
>> THAT AT LEAST THERE WOULD BE
SOME HOPE.
>> FAIRLY EARLY ON WE REALIZED
THAT IT WASN'T GOING TO BE THE
CASE, AND IT WAS BASICALLY SET
UP FOR NOTHING.
>> WHEN -- HOW DO YOU -- HOW DO
YOU DEAL WITH SOMETHING LIKE
THAT AS A FIRST RESPONDER?
EVERYBODY THINKS ABOUT OBVIOUSLY
THE CHILDREN AND THE TEACHERS
AND ALL THOSE WHO LOST THEIR
LIVES AND THE PARENTS.
BUT THE THINGS THAT YOU GUYS
HAVE TO DEAL WITH, THERE IS -- I
MEAN IT NEVER LEAVES YOU.
>> NO.
>> YOU HAVE A JOB TO DO AT THE
TIME, AND THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE
THINKING ABOUT AT THE TIME.
YOU REALLY DON'T THINK TOO MUCH
ABOUT THAT KIND OF STUFF
UNTIL --
>> UNTIL LATER?
>> UNTIL LATER.
AND EVEN NOW THERE IS STILL A
LOT OF STUFF GOING ON.
AND I THINK IT'S GOING TO GET
WORSE BEFORE IT GETS BETTER.
>> I'VE ALWAYS FOUND THAT IN THE
FIRST COUPLE OF DAYS, AND WHEN
THERE IS A LOT OF FOCUS AND
ATTENTION THE ADRENALINE KIND OF
GETS YOU THROUGH.
BUT IT'S OFTEN IN THE WEEKS
AFTER WHEN PEOPLE KIND OF GO
AWAY AND THE REST OF THE WORLD
KEEPS SPINNING AND RETURNS TO
SOME SEMBLANCE OF NORMAL, THEN
IT'S THIS TOWN WHICH IS GOING TO
BE LEFT WITH AN OPEN WOUND.
>> THERE IS GOING TO BE A NEW
NORMAL I THINK.
THE OLD NORMAL A WEEK AGO,
THAT'S GONE, I BELIEVE.
>> A LEVEL OF COMPLACENCY ALL
THESE YEARS, THAT'S GONE.
AND WE'LL BE SCARRED FOREVER
FROM THIS, I THINK.
>> WE WILL RECOVER, OBVIOUSLY.
LIKE ROB SAID, WE'RE A
CLOSE-KNIT COMMUNITY.
WE WILL RECOVER SOMEWHAT.
BUT LIKE ROB SAID, THE SCAR IS
NOT GOING TO GO AWAY.
>> THE SCARS HEAL, BUT THEY
REMAIN.
AND THEY'RE ALWAYS THERE.
I REALLY APPRECIATE ALL YOU'VE
DONE, AND THANK YOU VERY MUCH
FOR TALKING.
I KNOW IT'S NOT EASY.
THANK YOU.
I WISH YOU THE BEST.
>> THANK YOU.
>> THANKS.
WITH THE COMMUNITY REALLY UNITED
IN GRIEF, ONE PIECE OF THE PLAN
TO MOVE BEYOND THE TRAGEDY IS
TAKING SHAPE TODAY.
AND WHEN I SAY "MOVE BEYOND," I
DON'T WANT TO MAKE IT SOUND LIKE
PEOPLE WANT TO FORGET, BECAUSE
THEY DON'T.
THIS TOWN WILL NEVER FORGET, AND
THEY JUST NEED TO TRY TO FIGURE
OUT A WAY TO CONTINUE ON AND
HONOR THE MEMORY OF THOSE WHO
THEY'VE LOST.
HOW NEWTOWN'S NEIGHBORS ARE
HELPING SANDY HOOK STUDENTS FEEL
SAFE WHEN THEY RETURN TO CLASS.
I'LL SPEAK WITH THOSE WHO LOST
LOVED ONES IN PREVIOUS MASS
SHOOTINGS ABOUT THEIR HEALING
PROCESS.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
SO, THIS BOARD
GIVES ME RATES FOR
PROGRESSIVE DIRECT AND OTHER
CAR INSURANCE COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
CALL OR CLICK TODAY.
>>> WELL, NEWTOWN SCHOOLS WILL
REOPEN TOMORROW, BUT NOT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY, OBVIOUSLY.
INSTEAD ANOTHER, A FORMER SCHOOL
WILL REOPEN EVENTUALLY FOR THE
STUDENTS WHO SURVIVED THE
SHOOTING.
THE MOVE WILL ALLOW SANDY HOOK
STUDENTS TO RETURN TO CLASS
WITHOUT HAVING TO RETURN TO THE
SITE OF THE TRAGEDY.
CONNECTICUT'S GOVERNOR DAN
MALLOY ANNOUNCED THE MOVE TODAY
AT A VERY EMOTIONAL NEWS
CONFERENCE, WHERE HE ALSO
RECOUNTED THE MOMENTS AFTER THE
SHOOTING WHEN HE NEEDED TO
DELIVER TO THE PARENTS WHO WERE
WAITING FOR NEWS ABOUT THEIR
CHILDREN, WHEN HE NEEDED TO
DELIVER THE WORST POSSIBLE NEWS.
>> IT WAS EVIDENT TO ME THAT
THERE WAS A RELUCTANCE TO TELL
PARENTS AND LOVED ONES THAT THE
PERSON THAT THEY WERE WAITING
FOR NOT GOING TO RETURN.
AND THAT HAD GONE ON FOR A
PERIOD OF TIME, WELL AFTER THERE
WAS ANY EXPECTANCY THAT FAMILIES
WOULD BE REUNITED.
I MADE THE DECISION THAT TO HAVE
THAT GO ON ANY LONGER WAS WRONG.
SO I DID IT.
>> I TALKED TO LYNN McDONNELL.
KATE BALDWIN JOINS ME NOW.
I TALKED TO LYNN McDONNELL
EARLIER.
I TALKED TO HER AND HER HUSBAND
CHRIS THAN WAIT.
THEY THOUGHT MAYBE THEIR LITTLE
GRACE WAS IN SOME PLACE THAT WAS
SAFE.
AND THEN SLOWLY IT BEGAN TO DAWN
ON PEOPLE THAT THAT WAS NOT THE
CASE.
SO WHAT ARE THE PLANS NOW FOR
SCHOOLS?
>> IT REALLY STARTED KICKING
INTO ACTION THE SAME DAY AS THE
HORROR WAS UNFOLDING.
NO ONE WANTS TO SEND THE
CHILDREN BACK TO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
THEY KNOW THAT IT'S CLEARLY NOT
TIME FOR THAT.
IT'S STILL A CRIME SCENE RIGHT
NOW.
SO THEY MADE PLANS WITH THE
NEIGHBORING TOWN FOR A SCHOOL
JUST SIX MILES AWAY.
ALMOST -- IT'S VERY FORTUITOUS.
BUT THERE WAS AN EMPTY MIDDLE
THAT HAD BEEN CLOSED BECAUSE OF
DECLINING ENROLLMENT LAST YEAR.
SO THE NEIGHBORING TOWN MONROE,
THE CHIEF EXECUTIVE OF THE TOWN,
HE CALLED THEM RIGHT AWAY THAT
SAME DAY AND SAID IF YOU WANT
IT, IT'S YOURS.
AND SO THEY'VE BEEN WORKING
AROUND THE CLOCK.
CONTRACTORS FROM AROUND THE
REGION HAVE BEEN DONATING THEIR
TIME TO GET THIS FACILITY, IT'S
A FORMER MIDDLE SCHOOL UP TO
STUFF AND UP TO CODE.
THEY HAVE TO CHANGE, REALLY,
EVERYTHING.
THE BONES ARE STRONG.
IT'S A SCHOOL.
BUT THEY HAVE TO LOWER
EVERYTHING.
THEY HAVE TO REPLACE TOILETS TO
BE SMALL ENOUGH FOR CHILDREN,
FOR ELEMENTARY SCHOOL CHILDREN.
THEY HAVE TO LOWER TOWEL
DISPENSERS.
>> DO YOU KNOW WHEN THE KIDS ARE
GOING TO GO BACK?
>> THAT'S UP TO TOWN OFFICIALS.
THE MACHINE ROW OFFICIALS TOLD
ME THE BUILDING ITSELF COULD BE
READY AS SOON AS TOMORROW.
THEY'VE BEEN WORKING AROUND THE
CLOCK TO GET IT READY.
BUT HEN THE SCHOOL SYSTEM IS
READY TO ASK THE CHILDREN TO
COME BACK TO SCHOOL, THAT'S UP
TO NEWTOWN SCHOOL OFFICIALS.
AND THIS FRIDAY IS SUPPOSED TO
BE THE LAST DAY OF SCHOOL BEFORE
THE HOLIDAY BREAK.
SO IT COULD BE, YOU KNOW, ONLY A
DAY OR TWO THAT THEY'LL BE IN
CLASS.
BUT SOME ARE SAYING, WE ACTUALLY
TALKED ABOUT IT WITH SANJAY
EARLIER, SOME ARE SAYING THAT'S
REALLY WHAT THE KIDS NEED TO DO.
THEY NEED TO GET BACK INTO THAT
ROUTINE.
BECAUSE ONCE THEY GET INTO THAT
ROUTINE AND BACK INTO SCHOOL AND
BACK FOCUSING ON THEIR SCHOOL
AND WORK, THAT'S GOING TO HELP
THEM HEAL FASTER.
>> AND OF COURSE THERE ARE GOING
TO BE A NUMBER OF FUNERALS ALL
THIS WEEK.
>> YES.
>> WE SAW TWO TODAY.
I KNOW GRACE McDONNELL, THAT THE
WAKE IS ON THURSDAY.
I THINK THE FUNERAL IS GOING TO
BE ON FRIDAY.
SO WHETHER THE KIDS ARE GOING TO
GO TO FUNERALS OBVIOUSLY, AND
OBVIOUSLY THEY'RE GOING TO NEED
TO HAVE COUNSELORS ON SCENE.
THAT FIRST DAY FOR THE KIDS COME
BACK TO THAT SCHOOL.
>> SO TOUGH.
AND I'VE BEEN TOLD THEY'RE EVEN
TALKING TO TEACHERS ABOUT HOW TO
TALK TO STUDENTS ON THE FIRST
DAY BACK.
>> SURE.
>> IF THERE ARE QUESTIONS, IF
VIOLENCE IS BROUGHT UP OR
WHATEVER QUESTIONS MAY COME UP.
YOU KNOW, CHILDREN SEE AND KNOW
MORE THAN THEY GIVE OFF, YOU
KNOW.
THEY'RE VERY PERCEPTIVE,
ESPECIALLY AT THAT AGE.
THEY'VE BEEN WORKING WITH
TEACHERS, AND WE SAW IT WHEN WE
WERE DRIVING AROUND.
THEY SAID THAT CHALK HILL, THAT
MIDDLE SCHOOL WHERE THE SANDY
HOOK CHILDREN ARE GOING TO BE
GOING, IT WILL LIKELY BE THE
MOST SECURE SCHOOL IN THE STATE.
AND THEY'RE VERY SERIOUS
ABOUT -- THERE IS POLICE PATROL
AT EVERY SCHOOL.
THEY SAID UNFORTUNATELY THAT MAY
NOW BE THE NEW NORMAL AS THEY'RE
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHAT TO DO
AND HOW TO PROTECT THEIR KIDS.
>> KATE, I APPRECIATE THAT
THANKS FOR ALL THAT LATEST
INFORMATION.
SADLY, THIS IS NOW THE LATEST
MASS SHOOTING TO BRING THE
COUNTRY TOGETHER IN GRIEF.
AND WHILE MANY AMERICANS ARE
STILL STRUGGLING TO GRASP THE
ENORMITY OF WHAT HAPPENED IN
NEWTOWN, OTHER FAMILIES ALREADY
KNOW WHAT IT'S LIKE TO FACE THIS
SORT OF NIGHTMARE.
WE THOUGHT IT WORTHWHILE TO TALK
TO SOME OF THE PEOPLE WHO HAVE
BEEN THROUGH THIS KIND OF A
TRAGEDY BEFORE.
AND SADLY, THERE ARE MANY OF
THEM.
HE LOST HIS FATHER AT THE SIKH
TEMPLE SHOOTING IN OAK CREEK,
WISCONSIN IN WISCONSIN.
WE TALKED TO OMERDEEP A LOT.
AND AND THE TUCSON SHOOTING THAT
ALSO INJURED GABBY GIFFORDS
NEARLY TWO YEARS AGO.
ROXANA IS JOINING ME NOW.
AND OMERDEEP IS GOING TO BE
JOINING ME IN JUST A MOMENT.
ROXANNA, WHEN YOU HEARD THE
NEWS, WHAT WAS YOUR REACTION?
IT MUST JUST ALL BRING IT BACK.
>> I WAS DEVASTATED.
I WAS HEARTBROKEN FOR ALL THE
FAMILIES AND THE VICTIMS.
IT JUST BROUGHT IT ALL BACK TO
ME, AND I WAS VERY, VERY SAD.
>> LET ME JUST GIVE YOU A MIC
BECAUSE I THINK WE'RE HAVING AN
ISSUE HERE.
HOLD ON TO IT.
THERE ARE NOW SO MANY PARENTS
WHO ARE GOING THROUGH EXACTLY
WHAT YOU WENT THROUGH.
WHAT IS YOUR ADVICE TO THEM?
I MEAN, IT'S A JOURNEY THAT
DOESN'T END, THIS JOURNEY OF
GRIEF.
>> WELL, ALL I CAN SAY IS TO DIG
DEEP WITHIN YOURSELF.
AND IF YOU'RE A PERSON OF FAITH,
JUST TO PRAY REALLY HARD AND
SURROUND YOURSELF WITH LOVED
ONES OR FAMILY AND FRIENDS.
AND THINGS WILL GET BETTER IN
TIME.
BUT UNFORTUNATELY, IT'S A PAIN
THAT NEVER GOES AWAY.
I HAVE A HOLE IN MY HEART, AND I
WILL FOREVER.
BUT I'M JUST PRAYING FOR THEM,
THEY FIND SOME KIND OF PIECE.
>> AND I WANT TO BRING IN
OMERDEEP.
FOR YOU, YOUR LOSS WAS MORE
RECENT.
OBVIOUSLY, WHEN YOU HEARD OF
THIS, IT MUST HAVE ALL BROUGHT
IT BACK.
>> OH MY GOD, IT WAS SHOCKING.
WHEN WE HEARD IT, WE HAD A
TODDLER RUNNING AROUND THE
HOUSE.
AND WE JUST STARED AT HIM.
MY WIFE LOOKED AT ME.
I WAS A FORMER TEACHER.
SHE GOES HE WOULDN'T HAVE EVEN
RAN.
HE WOULD HAVE BEEN IN SHOCK.
WE STARTED CRYING.
WE COULDN'T STOP.
>> WHAT IS IT LIKE WHEN THERE IS
A LOT OF FOCUS IN THE IMMEDIATE
DAYS AFTER THIS, BUT THEN
ULTIMATELY REPORTERS GO AWAY,
AND A LOT OF THE WELL-WISHERS
AND THE COUNSELORS GO AWAY.
AND THE REST OF THE WORLD SORT
OF KEEPS SPINNING, BUT YOUR
WORLD HAS STOPPED?
I MEAN YOUR WORLD HAS COMPLETELY
CHANGED FOREVER.
HOW DO YOU COPE WITH THAT TIME
WHEN THE ADRENALINE FADES AWAY
AND THE REALITY SETS IN?
>> WELL, IN MY CASE, I WROTE A
BOOK, "AS GOOD AS SHE IMAGINED."
I STARTED A FOUNDATION IN MY
DAUGHTER'S NAME.
SO I'VE BEEN REALLY, REALLY BUSY
WITH THAT IT TAKES UP A LOT OF
MY TIME.
AND JUST GIVING BACK TO LESS
FORTUNATE CHILDREN IN OUR
COMMUNITY BY BUILDING
PLAYGROUNDS AND HELPING OUT THE
SCHOOLS WITH SMARTBOARDS AND
P.E. EQUIPMENT.
THAT HAS BEEN THERAPEUTIC AND
HEALING.
>> AMARDEEP, WHAT CAN COME OUT
OF THIS?
WE'VE SEEN FAR TOO MANY OF THESE
KINDS OF THINGS.
I KNOW YOU WANT SOMETHING TO
CHANGE.
SOMETHING'S GOT TO CHANGE.
>> I MEAN, THE NATIONAL DIALOGUE
HAS TO START.
ROXANNA AND I WITH MAYORS
AGAINST ILLEGAL GUNS.
AND WE JUST DID A WHOLE EVENT
WITH MAYOR BLOOMBERG THIS
MORNING OR THIS AFTERNOON.
AND, I MEAN, IT'S NOT JUST THE
GUNS THAT IS THE PROBLEM,
THOUGH.
AND IT'S BECOME LIKE A DEEP DOWN
ROOTED SOCIETAL ISSUE.
AND WE NEED TO KEEP THAT
CONVERSATION GOING.
AND FOR US, WE STARTED A
DOCUMENTARY CALLED NURSERY
CRIMES.
AND WE'RE GOING OUT OF OUR WAY
TO GO FIGURE OUT WHAT IS
HAPPENING AT A YOUNGER AND
YOUNGER AGE, AND HOW WE CAN FIND
THOSE PEOPLE THAT ARE ALMOST AT
THIS POINT OF SOCIOPATHY AND
THEN STOP IT AND BRING THEM
BACK.
>> THERE IS ALSO OBVIOUSLY
ISSUES OF MENTAL HEALTH THAT
NEED TO BE ADDRESSED.
IS THAT A CONCERN OF YOURS AS
WELL?
>> OH, ABSOLUTELY.
OUR SYSTEM HAS FAILED SO MANY
YOUNG PEOPLE.
AND, YOU KNOW, I THINK CONGRESS
AND THE PRESIDENT HAS TO WORK
REALLY, REALLY HARD TO COME UP
WITH A, YOU KNOW, GUN VIOLENCE
PROTECTION PLAN AND A BETTER
HEALTH CARE SYSTEM SO THESE KIND
OF SENSLESS TRAGEDIES DON'T
HAPPEN.
>> IT SEEMS LIKE SO MANY EVEN
PARENTS WHO KNOW THEIR CHILDREN
HAVE AN ISSUE, OR KNOW THEIR
YOUNG KIDS IN THEIR 20s HAVE AN
ISSUE, THEY CAN'T GET HELP
UNLESS THAT CHILD IS PROVEN TO
BE VIOLENT OR A THREAT TO
THEMSELVES OR TO OTHERS.
>> I MEAN, IT'S SAD.
MOST OF THE TIME THE CHILD
ACTUALLY HAS TO COMMIT A CRIME
BEFORE THEY'RE GOING TO BE ABLE
TO GET HELP.
AND A LOT OF TIMES MEDICAL
PEOPLE HAVE TO SAY THAT HEY, I
CAN'T HELP THEM UNTIL THEY DO
SOMETHING X, Y, Z BAD.
AND THAT'S A BROKEN SYSTEM.
BECAUSE WE CAN SEE YOUNGER AND
YOUNGER KIDS DOING SMALL THINGS
THAT WOULD BE SOCIOPATHIC OR
ISOLATED.
AND WE CAN GET THEM TO CONVERT
OR REVERT.
>> WHAT HAS BEEN IT BEEN LIKE
FOR YOU JUST TO WALK AROUND THIS
TOWN AND TO SEE -- TO SEE THE
OUTPOURING OF -- PEOPLE JUST
WANT TO BE HERE AND HUG ONE
ANOTHER.
>> I THINK IT'S VERY, VERY
SPECIAL.
IT'S SO HEARTBREAKING WHAT
HAPPENED HERE.
IT'S JUST DEVASTATING.
BUT TO SEE ALL THE PEOPLE COME
TOGETHER, WE JUST KNOW THAT
THERE HAS TO BE CHANGE AND HOPE
WITH THAT.
>> I APPRECIATE BOTH OF YOU
TALKING.
AND ANY WANTED TO BE HERE TOO.
YOU WERE WALKING AROUND TO SEE
THE MEMORIALS.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
IT WAS AMAZING TO SEE ALL THE
SUPPORT IN THE COMMUNITY TO COME
OUT.
AND IT'S JUST ONE OF THOSE
THINGS THAT'S -- IT'S ONE THING
WHEN YOU LOOK AT A KID THAT
FALLS VICTIM TO THIS.
THEY CAN'T VOTE.
THEY CAN'T SIGN A PETITION.
THEY CAN'T GO OUT AND RALLY.
BUT IT'S US, THE ADULTS AT THIS
POINT IN TIME.
I MEAN, WE JUST SAW 20 INNOCENT
LIVES TAKEN WITH NO POINT TO IT.
IT WAS PERVERTED BEYOND BELIEF.
AND IT'S UP TO US TO PROTECT
THOSE CHILDREN AND THE CHILDREN
THAT ARE UP TO COME, YOU KNOW.
>> AMARDEEP, I APPRECIATE YOU
BEING HERE.
ROXA
ROXANA, THANK YOU.
>>> THE INVESTIGATORS LOOK AT
THE COMPUTER'S KILLER.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI JOINS US WITH
THAT NEXT.
[ Male Announcer ] Alka-Seltzer
Plus PRESENTS THE Cold Truth.
I HAVE A COLD,
AND I TOOK NYQUIL,
BUT I'M STILL "STUBBED" UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT DOESN'T HAVE A DECONGESTANT.
NO WAY.
[ Male Announcer ] SORRY.
Alka-Seltzer Plus FIGHTS
YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A FAST ACTING
DECONGESTANT
TO RELIEVE YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
[ sighs ] THANKS!
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus.
♪ OH
WHAT A RELIEF IT IS! ♪
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
AND SAVE $1
VISIT Alka-Seltzer ON FACEBOOK.
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
ALRIWOAH! DID YOU GET THAT?
AND...FLIP!
YEP, LOOK AT THIS. IT TAKES
LIKE 20 PICTURES AT A TIME. I
NEVER MISS ANYTHING.
ISN'T THAT AWESOME?
UH THAT'S REALLY COOL.
YOU SHOULD UPLOAD THESE.
I KNOW, RIGHT?
THAT IS REALLY AMAZING.
THE PICTURES ARE SO CLEAR.
KEVIN'S A HANDSOME DEVIL
THAT PHONE DOES EVERYTHING!
SEARCH DOG TRICKS.
OKAY, SEE IF WE CAN TEACH
HIM SOMETHING COOL.
LOOK AT HOW LAZY KEVIN IS.
KEVIN, GET IT TOGETHER DUDE
CMON, KEVIN
TAKE 20 PICTURES WITH BURST
SHOT ON THE GALAXY S3.
>>> AS THE NEWTOWN COMMUNITY
CONTINUES TO STRUGGLE TO MAKE
SENSE OF THIS TRAGEDY, IF THAT'S
AT ALL POSSIBLE, POLICE ARE
TRYING TO PUT THE PIECES
TOGETHER AND FIGURE OUT JUST
WHAT HAPPENED.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI IS HERE WITH THE
LATEST.
WHAT ARE WE LEARNING ABOUT THE
INVESTIGATION AT THIS POINT?
>> WELL, THE NEWEST PART ABOUT
THE INVESTIGATION, ANDERSON, IS
THAT IT TURNS OUT THE SUSPECTED
SHOOTER IN THIS CASE DID GO TO
GUN RANGES A NUMBER OF TIMES
OVER THE LAST SEVERAL YEARS, AND
AS RECENTLY AS SIX MONTHS AGO.
NOW, HE MIGHT HAVE GONE MORE
RECENTLY THAN THAT, BUT THEY'RE
NOT THROUGH LOOKING AT ALL THE
GUN RANGES AND CONTACTING ALL OF
THEM TO FIND OUT ALL THE
INFORMATION.
>> DID HE GOOD ALONE?
>> WELL, THEY DID FIND EVIDENCE
THAT HE WENT AT LEAST ONCE WITH
HIS MOTHER.
THEY HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE TO PROVE
WHETHER THEY ACTUALLY WENT
TARGET SHOOTING TOGETHER AT THAT
GUN RANGE.
BUT THEY DID BOTH GO TOGETHER AT
LEAST ONCE.
>> AND HAVE THEY FOUND
INFORMATION AT HOME, ON
COMPUTERS OR ANYTHING LIKE THAT
THAT WE KNOW?
>> YEAH, THEY'VE BEEN EXAMINING
COMPUTERS THAT HAVE BEEN FOUND
AT THE HOME.
AND OUR SOURCES TELL US THAT
THEY WEREN'T IN GOOD ORDER --
THEY WERE SMASHED TO
SMITHEREENS.
AND NOW THEY LITERALLY HAD TO
PICK UP THE PIECES, TAKE THEM TO
THE CRIME LAB.
AND NOW THEY'RE GOING THROUGH
EVERYTHING, TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT WEBSITES HE VISITED, DID HE
TALK TO ANYBODY, WAS HE IN ANY
CHAT ROOMS, LEAVE ANY MESSAGES.
DID HE PLAY ANY VIDEO GAMES?
SO THEY'RE LOOKING AT ALL THESE
THINGS TO TRY TO FIGURE OUT.
AGAIN, IT'S ALL PART OF THE BIG
PICTURE HERE AND LOOKING FOR A
POSSIBLE MOTIVE.
>> AND AT THIS POINT, IS IT
KNOWN WHY THAT SCHOOL, WHY HE
PICKED THAT SCHOOL?
>> NO, IT ISN'T.
AND IN FACT, I TALKED WITH A
YOUNG MAN WHO WENT TO HIGH
SCHOOL WITH HIM, AND HE WENT
DOWN TO THE MEMORIAL TODAY
BECAUSE HE CAN'T BELIEVE WHAT
HAPPENED AND FEELS SO AWFUL FOR
THE CHILDREN.
BUT HE SAID THAT WHEN HE KNEW
HIM IN HIGH SCHOOL FOR ONE YEAR,
THEY WERE IN THE TECH CLUB
TOGETHER.
THEY LOVED PLAYING COMPUTERS.
HE LIKED PLAYING VIDEO GAMES.
AND HE MENTIONED TWO IN
PARTICULAR.
ONE CALLED "WAR CRAFT III".
>> SURE.
>> ANOTHER ONE CALLED
"STARCRAFT."
AND IT INVOLVES SETTING UP AN
ENEMY CAMP AND YOU KILL THE
SOLDIERS AND ALL OF THIS.
HE SAID EVERYONE KNEW HE WAS
SOCIALLY AWKWARD, AND THAT HE
HAD SOME ISSUES GOING ON,
SOMETHING WITH HIS PERSONALITY.
BUT AS GUYS, THEY NEVER REALLY
TALKED ABOUT IT.
>> AND THEY'RE DOING A COMPLETE
LOOK AT THE WEAPONS THAT HE HAD
ACCESS TO?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
AS WE KNOW, HE CAME ARMED TO THE
HILT, OFFICIALS SAY.
NOT ONLY DID HE COME WITH THAT
HIGH CAPACITY MILITARY
ASSAULT-STYLE WEAPON AND THOSE
TWO HANDGUNS, BUT HE HAD
30-ROUND MAGAZINES FOR EACH OF
THEM, AND SEVERAL OF THEM FOR
EACH OF THEM, PLUS EXTRA AMMO ON
TOP OF THAT.
AND THEY'RE TRACING THE COMPLETE
HISTORY OF HOW OFTEN HE USED
THOSE GUNS, MAYBE WHERE HE USED
THE GUNS.
MAYBE HE USED SOME OF THOSE AT
THE GUN RANGE.
BUT WE DON'T KNOW.
>> IS THERE ANY MORE INFORMATION
ABOUT THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER?
>> THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER.
WELL, WE'RE FINDING OUT A LITTLE
BIT MORE ABOUT HER DIVORCE,
THROUGH DIVORCE PAPERS, FOR
EXAMPLE.
SHE WAS GETTING ALIMONY FROM HER
HUSBAND, ABOUT $290,000 A YEAR,
$24,000 A MONTH.
THE MARRIAGE BROKEN DOWN BECAUSE
OF IRRECONCILABLE DIFFERENCES.
AND THAT HE WAS TO BUY A CAR FOR
HIS SON AND HIS EX-WIFE WAS TO
BE RESPONSIBLE FOR THE MORTGAGE.
>> IS THAT PRETTY MUCH ALL AT
THIS POINT?
>> YEAH.
I MEAN, THEY'RE STILL LOOKING
FOR THE MOTIVE AND TRYING TO
TALK TO FAMILY, TO FRIENDS TO
TRY TO PAINT A PICTURE OF WHAT
HE WAS ALL ABOUT.
THERE IS SOME TALK FROM ONE
RELATIVE THAT NANCY LANZA --
WELL, EVERYONE DESCRIBES HER
MORE AS A GUN COLLECT EITHER
THIS POINT.
WE HAVEN'T HEARD ANYTHING OTHER
THAN THAT, ANY PROOF OF ANYTHING
ELSE RIGHT NOW.
BUT SHE WAS CONCERNED ABOUT THE
ECONOMY, BUT THERE IS NO
EVIDENCE THAT IT WENT BEYOND
THAT, YOU KNOW.
>> RIGHT.
>> WHY SHE WAS COLLECTING THESE
GUNS.
>> RIGHT.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI, I APPRECIATE
THAT THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR THE
LATEST ON THAT.
AFTER EVERY MASS SHOOTING, OF
COURSE, WE'RE ALL LEFT WITH THE
SAME QUESTION WHY, WHY DID THIS
HAPPEN.
WHAT LEADS SOMEONE DOWN TO GUN
DOWN COMPLETE STRANGERS?
DO THESE KILLERS HAVE ANYTHING
IN COMMON?
WHAT DOES HISTORY ACTUALLY SHOW
US?
BECAUSE WHAT IS FASCINATING IS
OFTEN WHAT WE THINK WE KNOW
ABOUT THESE SHOOTINGS, ABOUT THE
PEOPLE WHO DO THEM, IT'S
ACTUALLY VERY DIFFERENT THAN
WHAT THE REALITY IS.
AND OFTEN IT TAKES YEARS TO
LEARN THE TRUTH ABOUT THESE
PEOPLE.
CHIEF MEDICAL CORRESPONDENT DR.
SANJAY GUPTA JOINS ME JUST
AHEAD.
[ Male Announcer ]
RESEARCH SUGGESTS CELL HEALTH
PLAYS A KEY ROLE
THROUGHOUT OUR LIVES.
One A Day Men's 50+
IS A COMPLETE MULTIVITAMIN
DESIGNED FOR MEN'S HEALTH
CONCERNS AS WE AGE.
IT HAS 7 ANTIOXIDANTS
TO SUPPORT CELL HEALTH.
One A Day Men's 50+.
IT HAS 7 ANTIOXIDANTS
TO SUPPORT CELL HEALTH.
Wooohooo....Hahaahahaha!
Oh...there you go.
I'm gonna stand
up to her!
No you're not.
I know.
You know Ronny folks who save
hundreds of dollars
switching to GEICO
sure are happy.
How happy are they Jimmy?
Happier than a witch in
a broom factory.
Get happy. Get GEICO.
Fifteen minutes could save you
fifteen percent or more.
>>> IT WAS DEVASTATING TO KNOW
THAT SOMEONE HAD COME INTO THE
SCHOOL WITH A GUN.
THAT ALONE WAS HORRIBLE ENOUGH,
BECAUSE IT'S A PLACE OF PEACE
AND JOY.
BUT NOW AS WE GO FORWARD AND
WE'VE LEARNED THE NAMES, AND NOW
WE'RE GOING THROUGH THE GRUELING
PROCESS OF THE FUNERALS, IT'S
VERY, VERY VERY HARD.
EVERYONE USES THE WORD HOLLOW.
THAT'S WHERE WE'RE AT RIGHT NOW.
>> WE'RE GOING TO CONTINUE TO
FOCUS ON THE VICTIMS OF FRIDAY'S
SHOOTING.
WE'RE GOING BRING YOU JUST A
LITTLE BIT OF MY INTERVIEW WITH
THE McDONNELL FAMILY, WHOSE
DAUGHTER GRACE WAS KILLED ON
FRIDAY.
WE'RE GOING TO PLAY THE WHOLE
INTERVIEW FOR YOU TOMORROW
NIGHT.
BUT WE'LL PLAY JUST A LITTLE BIT
A LITTLE BIT LATER ON TO HONOR
GRACE, AMAZING GRACE, AS WE
TALKED ABOUT IN THE INTERVIEW.
BUT THERE ARE MANY UNANSWERED
QUESTIONS THAT INVOLVES THIS
KILLER.
WHY TARGET AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL?
WHY THIS SCHOOL?
WHY DID HE MURDER 20 FIRST
GRADERS, LITTLE KIDS JUST 6 AND
7 YEARS OLD, YOUNG ENOUGH TO
BELIEVE IN SANTA CLAUS AND THE
TOOTH FAIRY.
AS WE SAID EARLIER TODAY,
AUTHORITIES ARE EXAMINING A
COMPUTER SMASHED IN THE GUNMAN'S
HOME.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI SPOKE ABOUT
THAT.
INVESTIGATORS MAY NEVER FIGURE
OUT WHAT HAPPENED.
SADLY, THOUGH, THERE IS A BODY
OF RESEARCH ON THESE KIND OF
KILLERS, ON MASS MURDERERS, AND
THE COMMON GROUND THEY MAY
SHARE.
DR. SANJAY GUPTA JOINS ME.
HE HAS BEEN LOOKING INTO THAT.
YOU'VE BEEN RESEARCHING
COMMONALITIES.
WHAT ARE THEY?
WHAT HAVE YOU FOUND?
>> ONE OF THE FIRST THINGS THAT
THESE MEDICAL INVESTIGATORS,
FORENSIC INVESTIGATORS WILL DO
IS TRY AND FIGURE OUTDO THEY FIT
A PARTICULAR TYPE.
AND THEY ALMOST ALWAYS DO, WHICH
IS INTERESTING.
THERE ARE TYPICALLY THREE TYPES
THAT WE'RE TALKING ABOUT HERE.
SOMEONE WHO ACTUALLY HAS
PSYCHOTIC TENDENCIES, SOMEONE
WHO HAS PSYCHOPATHIC TENDENCIES,
OR SOMEONE WHO HAS BEEN HEAVILY
TRAUMATIZED IN YOUTH.
JARED LOUGHNER, FOR EXAMPLE,
SOMEBODY WE REPORTED ON QUITE A
BIT.
HE CLEARLY HAD PSYCHOTIC
TENDENCIES.
AND ONE OF THE COLUMBINE KILLERS
HAD CLEAR CLUES DATING BACK OF
PSYCHOPATHIC TENDENCIES.
HE HAD SADISTIC BEHAVIOR.
HE HAD BEEN DELINQUENT WITH HIS
PARENTS QUITE A BIT.
AND I DON'T KNOW IF YOU REMEMBER
THIS, ANDERSON, BUT HE WAS
LAUGHING AT THE TIME THAT HE WAS
ACTUALLY COMMITTING THESE
MURDERS AT COLUMBINE HIGH
SCHOOL.
THE POINT IS THAT HARDLY ANYONE
EVER REALLY JUST SNAPS.
WE HAVE THE BENEFIT OF HINDSIGHT
IN THESE SITUATIONS.
BUT THE REAL POINT HERE IS THAT
WERE THERE SOME CLUES?
AND THERE ALMOST ALWAYS IS.
>> THAT NOTION OF JUST SNAPPING,
THAT DOESN'T REALLY TURN OUT TO
BE THE CASE, THAT USUALLY THERE
ARE PEOPLE WHO ACTUALLY --
SOMETIMES I'VE HEARD -- THERE
WAS A SECRET SERVICE REPORT DONE
THAT THEY ACTUALLY TALKED TO
OTHER KIDS, OTHER PEOPLE WHAT
THEY'RE GOING TO DO.
>> AND IF THEY DO THAT, A VERY
IMPORTANT POINT, IF THEY
ACTUALLY TALK TO SOMEONE AS
OPPOSED TO BEING ISOLATED, IT IS
A GREAT INHIBITOR OF CARRYING
OUT THE ACTIVITY.
ONCE YOU START TO TALK TO OTHER
PEOPLE, EITHER BECAUSE THEY TALK
YOU OUT OF IT, OR YOU YOURSELF
GET SOME GREATER CONTEXT OF WHAT
IT IS YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT IT
ALMOST ALWAYS INHIBITS THE
ACTIVITY.
SIMPLY TALKING ABOUT IT WITH A
LOVED ONE AND OTHER PEOPLE IN
THE SCHOOL.
COLUMBINE WAS UNUSUAL THAT WAY
BECAUSE THERE WAS TWO PEOPLE
TOGETHER.
BUT ALMOST ALWAYS IT IS A SINGLE
PERSON WHO HAS NOT DISCUSSED
THIS PLAN WITH ANYBODY ELSE.
>> YOU TALK ABOUT SOME OF THE
MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES.
ARE A LOT OF THEM ON MEDICATION,
OFF MEDICATION?
>> THIS IS REALLY INTERESTING.
ALMOST ALL OF THEM WERE ON SOME
TYPE OF MEDICATION.
AND IF YOU DIG A LITTLE BIT DEEP
WERE THAT, WHAT YOU FIND IS THAT
THERE IS A VULNERABLE PERIOD.
IT IS WHEN SOMEONE IS STARTING
MEDICATIONS OR WHEN THEY'RE
GOING OFF.
AND TYPICALLY THEY'RE
ANTIDEPRESSANTS.
NOT ALL PSYCHOTROPIC
MEDICATIONS.
AT THAT POINT WHEN THEY'RE
EITHER GOING ON OR GOING OFF,
THEY CAN BE A GREAT BENEFIT, BUT
YOU CAN HAVE INCREASED
IMPULSIVENESS, DECREASED
JUDGMENT AND LOSS OF TOUCH WITH
REALITY.
THOSE ARE THE THREE SYMPTOMS
THAT THEY DESCRIBED TO ME.
AND REMEMBER, ANDERSON, THEY
SHOULD BE MONITORED AT THAT
TIME.
BUT IN A MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEM
THE WAY IT IS NOW, THEY GET THE
PRESCRIPTION, AND HARDLY ANY
FOLLOW-UP.
>> DOCTORS HAVE TOLD ME THAT IF
YOU ARE ON ANTIDEPRESSANTS AND
YOU JUST STOP, THAT YOU SHOULD
NOT JUST STOP.
YOU REALLY NEED TO BE UNDER
SUPERVISION AND TAPER OFF.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> AND IT SEEMS LIKE SOME OF
THESE PEOPLE DIDN'T.
>> NO.
AND YOU KNOW, THE WHOLE
MONITORING NOTION INVOLVES
BUILDING TRUST WITH A
PSYCHIATRIST, BEING ABLE TO CALL
THAT PERSON, NOT SIMPLY GETTING
A PRESCRIPTION.
AND, YOU KNOW, THIS ISN'T TO
INDICT THE MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEM.
BUT IT'S BASICALLY SAYING THERE
IS NOT ENOUGH RESOURCES.
THEY CAN BARELY SEE THE PEOPLE
THAT THEY NEED TO SEE.
THIS IDEA OF BEING ABLE TO
MONITOR THEM, AGAIN, AT THESE
VULNERABLE PERIODS, IT'S NOT
HAPPENING.
I TALKED TO SEVERAL OF THEM.
THIS IS INCREDIBLY FRUSTRATING
FOR THEM.
>> ALSO OVER THE YEARS THERE HAS
BEEN A LOT OF FOCUS ON THE
RIGHTS OF THE PATIENT,
UNDERSTANDABLY, BECAUSE THERE
WERE ABUSES BEFORE.
I GUESS I WONDER, HAS IT GONE
TOO FAR?
I'VE HEARD FROM PARENTS WHO SAY
THEY KNOW THEY HAVE TROUBLES
WITH A CHILD OR WITH EVEN AN
ADULT CHILD, BUT THEY CAN'T DO
SOMETHING UNLESS THAT PERSON HAS
COMMITTED A CRIME OR IS PROVEN
TO BE DANGEROUS.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
EMINENT THREAT TO THEMSELVES OR
TO OTHERS.
WHAT AN UNBELIEVABLE STANDARD.
THINK ABOUT IT.
IT'S LIKE SAYING YOU WOULD HAVE
TO BE HAVING A HEART ATTACK TO
BE TREATED FOR YOUR HEART
DISEASE.
IT JUST DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
IT GOES AGAINST EVERYTHING WE
THINK OF AS DOCTORS.
THE OTHER OPTION IS BASICALLY TO
PUT THEM INTO THE CRIMINAL
JUSTICE SYSTEM.
AND NOW YOU'RE ASKING PARENTS TO
ESSENTIALLY CREATE A POLICE
RECORD FOR YOUR CHILD.
>> AND FRANKLY, THAT IS THE
REALITY THAT IS HAPPENING.
I MEAN, OUR PRISONS ARE FULL OF
PEOPLE WHO HAVE MENTAL ISSUES.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
PEOPLE ALWAYS TALK ABOUT THIS
NOTION THAT FAMILIES ARE DENYING
THE SNI
THE, SYMPTOMS THEY'RE IGNORING
THEM.
THEY'RE ANGUISH OVER WHAT IS
HAPPENING WITH THEIR CHILDREN.
EVEN IF THEY GET THE MEDS, THEY
ARE TO BE MONITORED, ESPECIALLY
WHEN GOING ON AND OFF.
AND THEY DON'T GET THAT.
THERE ARE SO MANY POTENTIAL
BREAKDOWNS IN THE SYSTEM.
THESE ARE FIXABLE PROBLEMS.
BUT IT'S NOT WORKING THE WAY IT.
>> AND THERE JUST NEEDS TO BE A
WILL AND A CONTINUED DISCUSSION.
OFTEN WE DISCUSS THESE THINGS IN
THE MEDIA IN THE WAKE OF
SOMETHING LIKE THIS AND STOP,
AND NOTHING EVER CHANGES.
SANJAY, I APPRECIATE THE REPORT.
A LOT OF PEOPLE THINK THAT
MASKED SHOOTERS ARE LONERS THAT
SIMPLY SNAP AS SANJAY SAID AND
GO ON KILLING SPREES.
IN HER BOOK "RAMPAGE," CATHERINE
NEWMAN SAYS IT'S NOT THAT
SIMPLE, NOT BY A LONG SHOT.
SHE HAS DONE A LOT OF RESEARCH
ON SCHOOL SHOOTINGS.
I APPRECIATE YOU BEING BACK ON
THE PROGRAM.
YOU'VE STUDIED RAMPAGE SHOOTINGS
LIKE THE ONE DATING BACK TO THE
1970s.
YOU SAY THERE ARE A LOT OF MYTHS
ABOUT THEM.
TALK TO ME ABOUT SOME OF THE
MYTHS.
>> ONE OF THE MYTHS IS THE IDEA
THAT PEOPLE SNAP.
BUT WE FOUND THAT SOMETIMES THEY
PLAN THESE THINGS AS MUCH AS
NINE MONTHS IN ADVANCE.
ANOTHER MYTH IS THAT THEY ARE
LONERS.
THEY'RE VERY RARELY LONERS, BUT
THEY'RE PEOPLE WHO HAVE A LOT OF
TROUBLE IN THEIR SOCIAL
INTERACTIONS THERE IS FRICTION
ALL AROUND THEM.
I HAVE TO SAY CONTRARY TO WHAT
YOU WERE JUST TALKING ABOUT, IN
THE CASE OF THE SHOOTERS WE
LOOKED AT, THEY WERE ALMOST
NEVER DIAGNOSED OR UNDER
TREATMENT.
AND SO THEY'RE OFTEN PEOPLE WHO
ARE COMPLETELY MISSED BY THE
MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEM.
AND WE FIND OUT ABOUT THEIR
MENTAL DISORDERS IN FORENSIC
SEGMENTS AFTER THE FACT.
WE ALSO DISCOVER THAT THEY TELL
PEOPLE A LOT ABOUT WHAT THEY'RE
PLANNING TO DO, BUT THEY DO SO
IN A WAY THAT IS VERY DIFFICULT
TO INTERPRET.
THEY SAY THINGS THAT ARE RATHER
VEILED AND CONFUSING.
AND BECAUSE WHAT THEY PLAN TO DO
IS SO OUTLANDISH AND SO
INCONCEIVABLE, THE PEOPLE AROUND
THEM DON'T REALLY KNOW HOW TO
INTERPRET WHAT THEY'VE HEARD.
SO THEY GET A LOT OF INFORMATION
CIRCULATING, BUT THAT DOESN'T
COME TO THE ADULTS WHO MIGHT BE
ABLE TO INTERVENE BECAUSE THE
KIDS HAVE A HARD TIME
INTERPRETING EXACTLY WHAT THOSE
VEILED WARNINGS MEAN.
>> I MEAN, WE SEEM TO SEE MOSTLY
MALES, YOUNG MALES COMMITTING
THESE HORRIBLE CRIMES.
IS THERE -- IS THERE A REASON
WHY THAT IS?
>> WELL, GIRLS DO OTHER THINGS,
I'M SORRY TO SAY THAT ARE
DAMAGING TO THEMSELVES.
BUT THEY TEND TO BE TURNING
INWARD, WHERE AS BOYS TEND TO BE
EXPLODING OUTWARD.
AND THAT'S PARTLY BECAUSE OF THE
IMAGES THAT THEY RECEIVE IN
POPULAR CULTURE, WHICH LIONIZE
THIS KIND OF VIOLENCE.
OBVIOUSLY NOT AGAINST CHILDREN,
BUT THE TRENCH COAT MAFIA, THE
SORT OF GUNMAN IS A FIGURE WE
RECOGNIZE.
AND FROM THE VIEWPOINT OF THESE
VERY MARGINAL BOYS, IT LOOKS
MORE APPEALING THAN THE DWEEBIE
LONER MISFIT.
AND SO WHAT THEY'RE SEEKING TO
DO MOST OF THE TIME IS SOLVE A
PROBLEM.
AND THE PROBLEM IS THEY DON'T
LIKE THE WAY OTHER PEOPLE
PERCEIVE THEM, AND THEY WANT TO
CHANGE IT.
AND WHEN THEY START TALKING
ABOUT SHOOTING PEOPLE, ALL OF
THE SUDDEN THOSE PEER GROUPS
START PAYING ATTENTION TO THEM.
AND NOW THEY'VE MADE A
COMMITMENT OR PROMISE WHAT
THEY'RE GOING TO DO, AND THEY
FIND THEY CAN'T BACK DOWN OUT OF
IT OR IT WOULD BE ONE MORE
SOCIAL FAILURE.
>> THAT'S INTERESTING.
SO IN SOME CASES, ACTUALLY
TALKING ABOUT IT, HAVING SAID
SOMETHING TO OTHERS, IT KIND OF
BUILDS UP THE MOMENTUM OR THE
PRESSURE FOR THEM TO ACTUALLY
ACT OUT ON IT?
>> IT DOES, ANDERSON.
I MEAN, THEY'RE USUALLY QUITE
AMBIVALENT ABOUT WHAT THEY'RE
GOING TO DO.
BUT WHAT PUSHES THEM PAST THE
AMBIVALENCE IS THE POSSIBILITY
THAT THEY MIGHT HAVE ONE MORE
COMPLETE SOCIAL DISASTER IN
WHICH THEY'VE MADE PROMISES, AND
NOW THEY'RE NOT GOING TO FULFILL
THEM, AND EVERYBODY IS GOING TO
BE LAUGHING AT THEM NOW.
AND IT IS AMAZING HOW MUCH THAT
MOTIVES THIS BEHAVIOR.
THEY'RE NOT THINKING ABOUT HOW
THEY'RE GOING TO KILL PEOPLE OR
DESTROY A TOWN.
THEY'RE THINKING ABOUT HOW OTHER
PEOPLE ARE GOING TO SEE THEM
DIFFERENTLY.
LOOK AT THE PICTURES OF THE
SHOOTER IN THE VIRGINIA TECH
CASE.
THERE HE WAS WITH GUNS BLAZING
AND A FLAK JACKET, AND HE LOOKS
LIKE RAMBO.
WELL, THAT LOOKS A LOT BETTER TO
HIM, I'M SORRY TO SAY THAN THE
DWEEBIE IMAGE OF THE REJECT AND
MISFIT.
>> AND JUST VERY BRIEFLY,
POLITICIANS TALK VIDEO GAMES.
DOES THAT -- HAVE YOU SEEN ANY
LINK?
>> THERE IS A LINK, ANDERSON,
BUT IT'S NOT THE LINK WE USUALLY
THINK OF.
OFTEN PEOPLE THINK THAT VIDEO
GAMES WILL SOMEHOW INSPIRE
PEOPLE TO FEEL RAGE AND GO OUT
AND ENACT IT.
INSTEAD, WHAT WE SAW WAS THAT
VIDEO GAMES JUST LIKE FILMS
PRESENT AN IMAGE OF MASCULINITY
THAT IS TIED TO VIOLENCE, AND
SORT OF GLAMOURIZES IT, AND
MAKES THESE BOYS WHO DON'T FEEL
VERY GLAMOROUS THAT IF THEY CAN
JUST DO THAT, OTHER PEOPLE ARE
GOING TO TURN AROUND AND LOOK AT
THEM DIFFERENTLY.
RATHER THAN INSPIRING A KIND OF
BOILING RAGE, WHAT IT DOES IS
PRESENT AN IMAGE OF HOW A
MASCULINE BOY, YOU KNOW, COULD
ACT AND BE NOTICED.
>> RIGHT.
INTERESTING.
KATHERINE NEWMAN, I APPRECIATE
YOU BEING ON.
SOME OF THE ADULTS IN NEWTOWN
ARE GETTING COMFORT FROM
VOLUNTEERS ON FOUR LEGISLATION.
HOW THESE AMAZING THERAPY DOGS
FOUND THEIR WAY HERE, IN JUST A
MOMENT.
TELL THEM
IT'S LIKE BEING NESTLED
IN AN EIGHT-WAY, ADJUSTABLE,
HEATED AND VENTILATED SEAT
SURROUNDED BY A 500-WATT
SOUND SYSTEM
WHILE FLOATING ON A SUSPENSION
MADE OF BILLOWY CLOUDS.
OR YOU COULD JUST HAND THEM
YOUR KEYS.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
>>> THE LITTLE GIRLS WITH
PRESIDENT OBAMA ARE EMILIE
PARKER'S SISTERS.
6-YEAR-OLD EMILIE WAS ONE OF THE
20 CHILDREN KILLED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
PRESIDENT OBAMA MET WITH
VICTIMS' FAMILIES AND FIRST
RESPONDERS LAST NIGHT BEFORE HE
SPOKE AT THAT MEMORIAL SERVICE.
>> YOU MUST KNOW THAT WHATEVER
MEASURE OF COMFORT WE CAN
PROVIDE, WE WILL PROVIDE IT.
WHATEVER PORTION OF SADNESS THAT
WE CAN SHARE WITH YOU TO EASE
THIS HEAVY LOAD, WE WILL GLADLY
BEAR IT.
NEWTOWN, YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
>> THEY ARE NOT.
SO MANY STRANGERS HAVE REACHED
OUT TO THIS BROKEN COMMUNITY,
INCLUDING SOME VOLUNTEERS WHO
DROVE HERE FROM THE MIDWEST WITH
THEIR THERAPY DOGS.
I'VE SAID BEFORE THAT WORDS CAN
SEEM SO SMALL AT TIMES LIKE
THIS.
AND THERE ARE NO WORDS, REALLY.
AND THAT'S WHAT IS SO GREAT
ABOUT DOGS.
HERE IS GARY TUCHMAN.
>> Reporter: NINE GOLDEN
RETRIEVERS ON THE MARCH, MAKING
THEIR WAY INTO A RECREATION
CENTER IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
FOR AN EMOTIONAL RESCUE TO HELP
COMFORT THE CHILDREN WHO
SURVIVED THE ATTACK AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY AND OTHER
CHILDREN IN TOWN.
THERAPEUTIC CANINES ARE
SPONSORED AND TRAINED BY
LUTHERAN CHURCH CHARITIES,
TRANSPORTED IN A VAN FOR A
900-MILE RIDE FROM ILLINOIS.
>> LET ME GIVE YOU A QUICK
INTRODUCTION TO THE DOGS HERE.
THIS IS CHEWY.
THIS IS RUTHIE, ABBY, PRINCE,
LUTHER.
>> MAGGIE.
HANNA.
>> BARNEY.
>> BARNEY, AND?
>> SHAMMY.
>> THESE ARE THE COMFORT DOGS.
>> Reporter: WHAT IS A COMFORT
DOG?
>> A COMFORT DOG IS ONE WHO
BRINGS COMFORT TO OTHER PEOPLE
WHEN THEY'RE SUFFERING OR
HURTING, OR BRING HAPPINESS TO
PEOPLE.
IT HELPS PEOPLE PROCESS THEIR
GRIEF.
THEY.
>> Reporter: SO IT'S SPECIALLY
TRAINED?
>> THEY ARE SPECIALLY TRAINED.
THESE ARE ALL SPECIALLY TRAINED
SERVICE DOGS.
WE DON'T USE THEM WITH DISABLED,
WE TRAIN THEM ADDITIONALLY TO
WORK WITH ALL DIFFERENT AGE
GROUPS AND PEOPLE.
TO SOME PEOPLE, AND WE'VE SEEN
THIS WITH CHILDREN, IT BRINGS A
SENSE OF CALMNESS IN A TIME OF
CONFUSION OR THE THEM DURING
THIS PERIOD.
TO SOME IT HELPS THEM PROCESS
THEIR GRIEF.
THEY'LL START CRYING, AND
THEY'LL HUG THE DOG.
AND TO SOME CHILDREN THEY'LL
COME UP SAD AND THEY'LL WALK
AWAY HAPPY.
>> Reporter: DO YOU KNOW THAT
LUTHER IS INCAPABLE OF BEING
MEAN?
LUTER IS A FRIENDLY DOG.
>> HAYDEN LOVES DOGS.
>> Reporter: WHEN DOES TRAINING
BEGIN TO BE A COMFORT DOG?
>> 5 1/2 WEEKS.
WE BUY PUPPIES AT 5 1/2 WEEKS
AND TURN THEM UPSIDE DOWN AND
HOW THEIR TEMPERAMENT IS.
>> Reporter: YOU TURN THEM
UPSIDE DOWN.
IF THEY ARE TURNED UPSIDE DOWN
AND THEY FLAIL, THEY CAN'T BE A
COMFORT DOG?
>> RIGHT.
OUR INITIAL SCREENING IS IF THEY
CAN BE RELAXED IN THAT POSITION,
THEN WE START THE NEXT PROCESS,
WHICH IS A TRAIN THEY'RE WORKS
WITH THEM ONE-ON-ONE FOR THE
NEXT EIGHT MONTHS TO A YEAR.
>> Reporter: AND WHERE ELSE HAVE
YOUR DOGS BEEN?
WHAT OTHER DISASTERS?
>> OUR DOGS A MONTH AGO WHEN
SANDY HIT, WE WERE OUT IN NEW
YORK AND NEW JERSEY.
WE HAVE BEEN IN INDIANA WITH THE
FLOODINGS.
WE HAD DOGS OUT IN JOPLIN,
MISSOURI.
>> Reporter: COME HERE!
THIS IS LUTHER.
HE IS A COMFORT DOG.
YOU CAN PET HIM.
IT SAYS RIGHT HERE, "PLEASE PET
ME."
HOW DO YOU FEEL WHEN YOU SEE A
CHILD COME UP TO ONE OF YOUR
DOGS WHO HAS BEEN IN THIS
SITUATION AND HAS A BIG SMILE ON
THEIR FACE?
>> TEARS.
THEY SMILE, I CRY.
>> Reporter: AND AMID THE
CONTINUING SADNESS HERE, THERE
WERE A LOT OF SMILES.
>> NOTHING BETTER THAN SEEING
DOG'S TAIL WAGGING LIKE THAT.
GARY TUCHMAN JOINS ME NOW.
THE DOGS WERE GREAT.
WERE YOU ABLE TO TELL THE HOW
THE PARENTS OF SANDY HOOK
REACTED TO THEM?
>> IT'S A LITTLE HARD TO HEAR
WHAT YOU SAID.
I THINK YOU'RE ASKING ABOUT HOW
THIS ALL WORKS.
LET ME TELL YOU MY UNSCIENTIFIC
FINES OF WHAT I LEARNED TODAY.
KIDS LOVE STUFFED ANIMALS,
ESPECIALLY BIG STUFFED ANIMALS.
THESE ARE BASICALLY BIG STUFFED
ANIMALS THAT WALK, WAG THEIR
TAILS AND LICK.
THEY DON'T BITE, THEY DON'T
GROWL, AND THEY WANT TO BE
PETTED 100% OF THE TIME.
IT'S VERY COMFORTING FOR THE
CHILDREN.
THIS IS THE EXACT ANTITHESIS OF
WHAT HAPPENED IN THIS TOWN ON
FRIDAY.
>> YEAH, GARY, I APPRECIATE THAT
REPORT.
BRINGING A SMILE TO A LOT OF
PEOPLE'S FACES TODAY.
GARY, THANKS.
>>> COMING UP NEXT, THE PARENTS
OF GRACE McDONNELL REMEMBER
THEIR DAUGHTER, THE AMAZING GIRL
THEY CALLED GRACIE.
>>> LOOKING AT PICTURES OF A
LIVE VIGIL AT THE MAKESHIFT
MEMORIAL THAT IS GROWING WITH
EACH PASSING DAY AND NIGHT.
EARLIER I MENTIONED I SPOKE WITH
THE PARENTS OF GRACE McDONNELL.
TODAY THEY INVITED US INTO THEIR
HOME.
THEY WANTED TO SPEAK ABOUT THEIR
DAUGHTER.
CHRIS AND LYNN McDONNELL HELPED
US TO GET TO KNOW GRACE AND THE
HAPPINESS THEY BROUGHT THEM AND
THEIR SON JACK AND EVERYONE SHE
TOUCHED.
WE'RE GOING TO BRING YOU THAT
FULL INTERVIEW TOMORROW.
WE'RE GOING TO SHARE SOME OF
WHAT THEY SAID WITH YOU TONIGHT.
LYNN McDONNELL TOLD US HOW THEY
DON'T WANT TO HAVE HATE IN THEIR
HEARTS WHAT HAPPENED.
LISTEN TO SOME OF WHAT SHE HAD
TO SAY.
>> I HAD SAID THAT TO JACK, THAT
IT'S OKAY TO BE ANGRY BECAUSE
SURE, WE HAVE ANGER AND WE'RE
UPSET AND WE DON'T KNOW WHY.
BUT I TOLD JACK THAT HE COULD
NEVER LIVE WITH HATE.
GRACE DIDN'T HAVE AN OUNCE OF
HATE IN HER.
AND SO WE HAVE TO LIVE THROUGH
GRACE AND REALIZE THAT HATE IS
NOT HOW OUR FAMILY IS AND
CERTAINLY NOT HOW GRACE IS.
AND I KNOW ALL THOSE BEAUTIFUL
LITTLE CHILDREN.
THEY DIDN'T HAVE ANY HATE IN
THEM EITHER.
SO WE'LL JUST TAKE THE LEAD FROM
THEM AND WE WILL NOT GO DOWN
THAT ROAD.
BUT WE'LL LET THEM GUIDE US.
>> DURING THE INTERVIEW, WE WERE
TALKING ABOUT GRACE.
AND I MENTIONED THAT ONE OF MY
FAVORITE SONGS IS "AMAZING
GRACE," AND THAT IT ALWAYS MAKES
ME CRY.
I SAID I'LL NEVER HEAR THAT SONG
AGAIN WITHOUT THINKING OF THEIR
GRACE.
AND LYNN LIKED THAT IDEA.
BUT SHE WANTED TO MAKE SURE THAT
WHEN YOU HEAR THAT SONG, YOU
SMILE, THAT YOU DON'T CRY.
ANOTHER THING THAT LYNN SAID
THAT GIVES HER SOME COMFORT TO
THINK THAT GRACE DIED WITH HER
FRIENDS, AND THAT THEY WERE
HOLDING HANDS WHEN THEY DIED.
SHE LIKES TO THINK OF THEM ALL
IN HEAVEN, ALL 20 OF THOSE
LITTLE CHILDREN, ALL HOLDING
HANDS TOGETHER RIGHT NOW.
♪ AMAZING GRACE HOW SWEET THE
SOUND ♪
♪ THAT SAVED A WRETCH LIKE ME
♪ I ONCE WAS LOST BUT NOW I'M
FOUND ♪
♪ WAS BLIND BUT NOW I SEE
♪ THROUGH MANY DAYS DANGERS,
TOILS, AND SNARES, WE HAVE
ALREADY COME ♪
♪ TWAS GRACE THAT BROUGHT US
SAFE THUS FAR ♪
♪ AND GRACE WILL LEAD US HOME
♪ AMAZING GRACE HOW SWEET THE
SOUND, THAT SAVED A WRETCH LIKE
ME ♪
♪ I ONCE WAS LOST BUT NOW I'M
FOUND, WAS BLIND BUT