SEIZED.
>> WITHOUT ELABORATING CAN YOU
SAY ARE THERE PIECES OF THE
PUZZLE MISSING THAT WILL MAKE
THIS MORE DIFFICULT TO TELL?
>> ARE THERE PIECES, YES,
MISSING, THAT WE HAVEN'T HAD A
CHANCE TO FINISH YET.
THE FORENSIC PART IS AN
IMPORTANT PART.
THAT'S NOT DONE YET.
THAT'S BEING WORKED ON, BUT NOT
DONE YET.
THE WITNESSES THAT NEED TO BE
INTERVIEWED, THERE'S AN IMMENSE
NUMBER OF WITNESSES THAT NEED TO
BE INTERVIEWED.
THAT'S NOT COMPLETED THERE.
THERE ARE WEEK'S WORTH OF WORK
WE HAVE LEFT IN ORDER TO
COMPLETE THIS.
WHAT I WOULD LIKE TO DO IS SAY
THAT WE WILL COME BACK IN A
COUPLE HOURS.
I APOLOGIZE FOR HAVING YOU OUT
HERE IN THE INCLEMENT WEATHER.
WE ARE ALSO.
BUT I WANT TO GET THE
INFORMATION FROM THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER'S OFFICE AND CONFIRM
THAT.
I WANT TO GET -- SEE IF I CAN
GET MORE DETAIL RELATIVE TO THE
PRESIDENTIAL VISIT AND WHAT
LOGISTICS OF THAT WILL BE THIS
AFTERNOON AND ANY UPDATES THAT I
GET FROM THE MAJOR CRIME
COMMANDERS OF THE DEPARTMENT I
WILL BRING THAT BACK TO YOU.
>> CAN YOU SAY WHAT FEDERAL
CRIME IS BEING BROKEN BY THOSE
POSING ON SOCIAL MEDIA.
>> FEDERAL AUTHORITIES.
I DON'T KNOW.
WE'LL BE BACK IN A COUPLE HOURS.
PLEASE STAY DRY.
>> SO THERE YOU HAVE IT.
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
SPOKESMAN LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE
UPDATING US.
SOLEDAD, VERY INTERESTING
DEVELOPMENT.
APPARENTLY ALL THESE FALSE
SOCIAL MEDIA REPORTS ALLEGEDLY
SUPPOSEDLY FROM THIS KILLER OUT
THERE AND THE WARNING FROM THIS
POLICE CHIEF, THE WARNING IS
SPECIFIC, WARNING BEING IF YOU
GET ENGAGED AND CIRCULATE THESE
FALSE REPORTS WITH THREATS OUT
THERE, YOU ARE VIOLATING THE LAW
AND THEY WILL GO AFTER YOU?
>> YEAH.
HE WAS TOUGH ON THAT.
ONE OF THE THINGS HE SAID, WHILE
NOT SPECIFICALLY REFERENCING ANY
SPECIFIC SOCIAL MEDIA REPORTS,
HE SAID THAT THERE IS ERRONEOUS
INFORMATION COMING OUT, ALL
THEIR INFORMATION IS ON THEIR
OFFICIAL WEBSITE AND NOT TO
TRUST ANYTHING THAT WAS JUST
BEING REPEATED OR CREATED ON
SOCIAL MEDIA.
HIGHLIGHTING, OF COURSE, THAT
THERE HAD BEEN CONTRADICTORY
INFORMATION, JUST WRONG
INFORMATION.
VERY TOUGH ON THAT AS YOU HEARD
IN THAT PRESS CONFERENCE, WOLF?
>> YEAH.
BECAUSE SOME OF THESE SOCIAL
MEDIA SITES I'VE SEEN ONE OR TWO
OF THEM OVER THE PAST DAY OR SO,
AND THEY'RE MAKING THESE
ACCUSATIONS AND THESE THREATS
OUT THERE AND SCARE SOMETHING
FOLKS AND THESE ARE TOTALLY
OBVIOUSLY ERRONEOUS.
THE AUTHORITIES ARE GOING TO GO
AFTER THEM.
THE OTHER THING WE HEARD IS THAT
THEY'RE REALLY CONCERNED ABOUT
KIDS GOING BACK TO SCHOOL
TOMORROW AND TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT HOW BEST TO DO THAT?
>> YEAH.
I THINK THAT'S BEEN A QUESTION
THAT ACTUALLY A LOT OF THE
PARENTS HERE HAVE HAD EVEN RIGHT
AFTER THIS HORRIBLE TRAGEDY
HAPPENED ON FRIDAY.
I MEAN WHAT DO YOU DO?
THE SCHOOL IS A CRIME SCENE AND
EVEN WHEN IT'S NO LONGER A CRIME
SCENE, YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
CHILDREN WHO EXPERIENCED AND
SEEN THE VERY WORST THINGS, HOW
COULD THEY POSSIBLY GO BACK TO
THEIR SCHOOL.
FOR THOSE WHO SURVIVED.
HOW COULD PARENTS BRING THEIR
CHILDREN BACK TO THIS SCHOOL.
I THINK THERE'S SOME BIG
QUESTIONS THEY'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO ANSWER IN TERMS OF LOGISTICS
AND WHAT WILL THEY DO.
IT'S A SIMILAR QUESTION THEY HAD
AT COLUMBINE THAT THEY'VE HAD IN
THE PAST.
SO I'M SURE THEY'LL BE TRYING TO
FIGURE OUT HOW OTHERS HAVE DONE
IT AS THEY MOVE FORWARD IN
DEALING WITH YET ANOTHER SORT OF
ANGLE ON THIS TRAGEDY THAT THEY
HAVE TO CONFRONT HERE.
>> YEAH.
I SUSPECT, YOU KNOW, JUST I
SUSPECT A LOT OF PARENTS WILL
SAY I'M GOING TO KEEP MY KID OR
KIDS HOME TOMORROW, THE NEXT
DAY, JUST OUT OF AN ABUNDANCE OF
PRECAUTION IF YOU WILL.
YOU CAN'T BLAME PEOPLE FOR BEING
NERVOUS GIVEN THE ENORMITY OF
THIS TRAGEDY.
THANKS VERY MUCH.
I KNOW YOU'RE GOING TO BE BACK,
I'M GOING TO BE BACK LATER BUT
OUR COVERAGE RIGHT NOW CONTINUES
WITH "STATE OF THE UNION WITH
CANDY CROWLEY."
>> GOOD AFTERNOON FOR THIS
SPECIAL EDITION OF STATE OF THE
UNION.
I'M CANDY CROWLEY.
MOMENTS AGO CONNECTICUT POLICE
WRAPPED UP A NEWS CONFERENCE AND
THEY SAID THERE HAS BEEN
MISINFORMATION ABOUT THE
INVESTIGATION INCLUDING CLAIMS
OF QUOTES FROM THE GUNMAN.
CONNECTICUT'S GOVERNOR TOLD CNN
THE GUNMAN GOT INTO THE SCHOOL
BY USING HIS ASSAULT WEAPON TO
SHOOT HIS OWN ENTRANCE INTO THE
BUILDING.
CONNECTICUT'S MEDICAL EXAMINER
SAID THE RIFLE FOUND AT THE
SCENE FRIDAY WAS THE PRIMARY
WEAPON IN THE MASSACRE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL BE HERE IN
NEWTOWN IN A FEW HOURS AND MEET
WITH THE VICTIMS' FAMILIES AND
WILL SPEAK AT AN INTERFAITH
VIGIL AT 7:00 P.M. EASTERN.
JOINING ME NOW, TWO CONNECTICUT
LAWMAKERS RICHARD BLOOMENLE THAT
AND CONGRESSMAN AND
SENATOR-ELECT CHRIS MURPHY WHOSE
DISTRICT INCLUDES NEWTOWN.
LET ME START WITH THE PAST
COUPLE DAYS FOR YOU ALL.
I KNOW YOU HAVE TALKED TO SOME
OF THESE FAMILIES WHO
UNDERSTANDABLY DON'T WANT TO BE
OUT IN PUBLIC EXCEPT FOR WHEN
THEY CHOOSE TO.
WE DID SEE ONE FATHER GO OUT.
CAN YOU TELL US AS SILLY AS THIS
MAY SEEM HOW ARE THEY HOLDING
UP?
WHAT'S SUSTAINING THEM AT THIS
POINT?
>> I DON'T THINK THAT ONE WORD
OR ONE SENTENCE OR ONE
DESCRIPTION WILL FIT ALL OF
THEM.
THEY ARE AS DIVERSE PROBABLY AS
THEY ARE HUMAN BEINGS.
I CAN TELL YOU THIS COMMUNITY
HAS DEMONSTRATED ITS STRENGTH
AND RESILIENCE AND RESOLVE IN
COMING TOGETHER.
WE WERE AT CHURCH SERVICE THIS
MORNING, WHICH WAS SO MOVING IN
ITS STATEMENT OF GRIEF BUT ALSO
COMING TOGETHER AND BONDING AND
STAYING STRONG.
I DON'T THINK I WILL EVER FORGET
THE CRIES OF GRIEF AND PAIN THAT
I SAW AT THE FIREHOUSE ON THAT
DAY AND AS A PARENT, AS A PERSON
JUST THE UNSPEAKABLE SADNESS
THAT PREVADSS THIS TOWN STILL
AND WILL GO ON FOR QUITE SOME
TIME.
>> AND YOU SAID THAT YOU'RE SOON
TO BE SENATOR ELECT, THIS IS
PART OF YOUR DISTRICT AND PEOPLE
HAVE ASKED ME TO DESCRIBE IT.
I SAID IF YOU EVER HAD A TRAIN
SET THAT RAN AROUND YOUR
CHRISTMAS TREE, THE VILLAGE
INSIDE IT WOULD BE NEWTOWN.
IT JUST IS THAT KIND OF A
VILLAGE.
YOU MUST KNOW PEOPLE HERE WHO
MUST BE DEEPLY AFFECTED, THE
MOST DIRECTLY AFFECTED AND WHAT
ARE YOU TAKING FROM THEM AND
WHAT DO THEY NEED?
>> YOU KNOW, THIS IS THE
QUINTESSENTIAL IDYLLIC NEW
ENGLAND COMMUNITY.
SMALL TOWN, PRIDES ITSELF ON ITS
CLOSENESS.
A LABOR DAY PARADE HERE THAT
HAPPENS THAT THE WHOLE STATE
COMES TO, THE BIGGEST IN THE
AREA, EVERY COMMUNITY GROUP AND
SCHOOL HAS A FLOAT, AND THE
CLOSENESS OF THE TOWN MAKES THE
GRIEVING EVEN WORSE.
EVERYONE KNOWS ONE OF THE YOUNG
LITTLE BOYS OR GIRLS THAT WAS
KILLED OR ONE OF THE ADULTS.
I FRANKLY THINK IT WILL BE ONE
OF THE THINGS THAT LETS THIS
COMMUNITY HEAL.
BECAUSE THERE'S A CLOSENESS,
EVERYONE IS SO TIGHT KNIT YOU'RE
SEEING THESE ACTS OF HUMANITY
SPILLING OVER IN THE LAST FEW
DAYS.
THAT'S GOING TO CONTINUE AFTER
THE LIGHTS LEAVE.
AND THE CLOSENESS OF THE
COMMUNITY HURTS BUT IT'S GOING
TO HELP US HEAL.
>> IT DOES.
TO HAVE PEOPLE WHO UNDERSTAND
WHAT YOU'RE GOING THROUGH
BECAUSE THEY'RE KIND OF GOING
THROUGH THE SAME THING EVEN IF
THEY'RE NOT DIRECTLY INVOLVED
THE PARENTS OF THE CHILDREN OR
RELATIVES OF THE ADULTS.
WE'RE LOOKING AT LIVE PICTURES
NOW OF WHAT'S GOING ON AROUND
NEWTOWN AND, OF COURSE, THERE
WILL BE THE VIGIL TONIGHT WITH
THE PRESIDENT.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT THIS FROM THE
POINT OF VIEW OF THE CONGRESSMAN
THAT REPRESENTS THE DISTRICT OR
THE SENATOR WHO REPRESENTS THE
STATE, DO YOU FEEL A SENSE OF
HELPLESSNESS LIKE WHAT CAN I DO?
BECAUSE IN EFFECT, THE ONE THING
THAT WOULD HELP, YOU CAN'T DO?
>> THE SENSE OF HELPLESSNESS IS
VERY REAL, BUT AT THE SAME TIME,
I'M HEARING FROM PEOPLE HERE IN
NEWTOWN, PARTICULARLY PEOPLE IN
LAW ENFORCEMENT, YOU KNOW, I
COME TO THIS ISSUE AND THIS
PLACE WITH A CAREER IN LAW
ENFORCEMENT 30 YEARS AS A
FEDERAL PROSECUTOR, UNITED
STATES ATTORNEY, AS WELL AS
STATE ATTORNEY GENERAL FOR 20
YEARS AND MY COLLEAGUES IN LAW
ENFORCEMENT SAY TO ME YOU HAVE
TO DO SOMETHING ABOUT ASSAULT
WEAPONS, HIGH CAPACITY
MAGAZINES, BOTH VERY
INSTRUMENTAL IN THIS CRIME AND
SO THERE IS A SENSE OF
HELPLESSNESS BUT ALSO A SENSE OF
MISSION THAT CITIZENS ON THE
STREETS, IN THE CHURCHES, ARE
SAYING TO ME, WE NEED TO DO
SOMETHING.
IT IS A CALL TO ACTION.
>> AND DO YOU FEEL THAT SAME
CALL TO ACTION?
BECAUSE WE'VE HAD A LOT OF
THESE.
I MEAN THERE WAS A YOUNG GIRL
THAT DIED IN TUCSON IN THE GABBY
GIFFORDS SHOOTING, A LOT OF
PEOPLE THAT DIED, BUT A
9-YEAR-OLD I THINK THAT DIED IN
THAT.
WE HAD A BABY KILLED IN THE
AURORA THEATER.
AND THIS IS SORT OF HORRIFIC
BEYOND IMAGINATION BECAUSE
THERE'S SO MANY YOUNG PEOPLE.
WE'VE HEARD THIS BEFORE.
AND THERE IS -- YOU KNOW, THERE
ARE PEOPLE SAYING WAIT A MINUTE,
CAN WE NOT DO ANYTHING JUST AS A
KNEE-JERK REACTION, WE NEED TO
THINK THIS THROUGH.
>> THE TIPPING POINT ON THESE
ISSUES WHETHER IT'S TAKING ON
ASSAULT WEAPONS OR PROVIDING
MORE COMPREHENSIVE MENTAL HEALTH
OR ADDRESSING THE SORT OF
CULTURE OF VIOLENCE THAT PROMPTS
SOMEBODY TO DO SOMETHING LIKE
THIS, THE TIPPING POINT SHOULD
HAVE HAPPENED A LONG TIME AGO.
IF THIS IS THE TIPPING POINT,
THEN WE'RE GOING TO GO DOWN TO
WASHINGTON AND PROMPT A
CONVERSATION THAT'S LONG
OVERDUE.
YOU KNOW, A YOUNG MAN GRABBED US
IN HIS CHURCH WE WERE IN SOBBING
SAYING, DON'T LET THIS HAPPEN
AGAIN.
I THINK OUR JOB HERE IS TO NOT
SET EXPECTATIONS TOO HIGH,
RIGHT.
THIS IS COMPLICATED.
AND SO WE CAN'T SOLVE IT WITH
LEGISLATION.
THERE ARE CERTAINLY GOING TO BE
LESSONS LEARNED.
>> ISN'T THAT IN THE END SORT OF
BALANCE YOU HAVE TO TAKE, IN
THAT A PERSON WITHOUT A HISTORY,
A CRIMINAL RECORD OR MENTAL
HEALTH RECORD OF ANY SORT, THAT
WOULD SUGGEST SOME KIND OF
VIOLENT TENDENCIES, CAN GET
GUNS.
SOME OF THE STRICTEST GUN LAWS
IN THE COUNTRY ARE HERE IN
CONNECTICUT AND THESE GUNS SO
FAR WE KNOW WERE PURCHASED
LEGALLY.
THERE IS A LIMIT TO WHAT ANYBODY
CAN DO TO STOP THIS SORT OF
THING?
>> WE ARE NEVER GOING TO BE ABLE
TO TAKE GUNS OUT OF THE HANDS OF
EVERY DERANGED PERSON, BUT WE
CAN DO SOMETHING.
AND I THINK THERE IS RENEWED
FOCUS ON THIS ISSUE.
I THINK THAT THIS INCIDENT,
HORRIFIC AND HORRIBLE AS IT IS,
ALMOST UNSPEAKABLE IN ITS
INHUMANITY AND CRUELTY, WILL
SPUR AND TRANSFORM THE NATIONAL
DISCUSSION ABOUT IT AND PERHAPS
LEAD TO MORE ACTION AND AT THE
VERY LEAST, PERHAPS DOING
SOMETHING ABOUT HIGH-CAPACITY
MAGAZINES.
>> AND FOR OUR VIEWERS THOSE ARE
THE THINGS YOU CAN ATTACH TO AN
ADULT WEAPON AND THEY FIRE OFF
100 ROUNDS IN JUST MINUSCULE
AMOUNT OF TIME.
A LOT OF THEM JAM AS WE SAW IN
AURORA, DID NOT HAPPEN THIS
TIME, THAT'S WHAT HE USED
APPARENTLY WAS THE HIGH-CAPACITY
MAGAZINE.
ONE OF THE THINGS YOU THINK
COULD BE DONE IS A BAN OR
LIMITATION OF SOME SORT ON THESE
HIGH-CAPACITY MAGAZINES.
WHAT ABOUT AN ASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN?
>> LISTEN, I THINK IT'S CLEAR
THAT NOBODY NEEDS TO HAVE
AMMUNITION THAT DISPENSES 30
ROUNDS IN A NUMBER OF SECONDS.
IT'S ALSO CLEAR THAT NOBODY THAT
HAS DEEP SEATED MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES SHOULD BE IN A WAITING
LINE TO GET SERVICES.
AND SO I THINK FOR US, YOU KNOW,
RIGHT NOW OUR FOCUS IS ON THE
VICTIMS AND HELPING PEOPLE
GRIEVE HERE.
WE DON'T EVEN HAVE THE FULL
POLICE REPORTS TO UNDERSTAND
WHAT HAPPENED INSIDE BUT ONCE WE
DO, I THINK THERE ARE GOING TO
BE -- I HOPE SOME PRETTY EASY
POLICY LESSONS THAT CAN FINALLY
START TO BRING US TOGETHER.
>> AND WHAT ABOUT JUST BRIEFLY
IN THE MINUTE OR SO WE HAVE
LEFT, WHAT ABOUT SCHOOL
SECURITY?
IN CONNECTICUT, IS A RELOOK
UNDER WAY?
BECAUSE IN THE END, A DOORBELL
OR A PASS WILL -- SOMEBODY -- I
MEAN THAT'S JUST NOT GOING TO
WORK CLEARLY.
SO WHAT IS THE ANSWER?
IS THE ANSWER TO HAVE POLICEMEN
AT THE DOORS OF ELEMENTARY
SCHOOLS?
IS THAT GOING TOO FAR.
WOULD ANYTHING GO TOO FAR IF IT
WOULD HAVE STOPPED THIS?
>> I THINK THERE WILL BE A TIME
FOR US, SITTING IN NEWTOWN IN
THE MIDST OF THIS GRIEF AND
SADNESS, TO BE MORE SPECIFIC
ABOUT WHAT WE CAN DO, WHAT WE
SHOULD DO AS A NATION.
MY COLLEAGUES ARE CALLING FROM
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY LITERALLY
TO NOT ONLY WISH US WELL, BUT
SAY, WE NEED TO DO SOMETHING AND
I THINK ALL OF THOSE SPECIFICS
WILL AWAIT A TIME WHEN MAYBE WE
CAN GIVE IT THE SENSIBLE,
THOUGHTFULLY, HOPEFULLY
EFFECTIVE ATTENTION IT DESERVES.
>> JUST AS A FINAL QUESTION, DO
YOU HEAR THAT FROM PEOPLE WHO
FORMALLY THOUGHT -- FORMERLY
THOUGHT WE DON'T NEED MORE LAWS,
WE NEED TO ENFORCE THE ONES WE
HAVE?
HAS THERE BEEN A CHANGE OF
THOUGHT?
>> I THINK IT'S TOO EARLY.
RIGHT HERE TO BE HONEST THERE
ARE PEOPLE COMING UP AND SAYING
MAKE SURE THIS DOESN'T HAPPEN
AGAIN, BUT THAT'S RARE.
MOST PEOPLE RIGHT NOW ARE JUST
SIMPLY TRYING TO DEAL WITH THE
TRAGEDY AND SO, YOU KNOW, THE
FAMILIES HERE I THINK WANT US TO
MAKE SURE THEY HAVE EVERYTHING
THEY NEED.
THE COMMUNITY HAS EVERYTHING WE
NEED.
AND WE'LL FIGURE OUT WHERE THIS
COMMUNITY WANTS US TO GO FROM A
POLICY STAND-POINT IN THE COMING
DAYS.
>> SENATOR-ELECT CHRIS MURPHY,
SENATOR BLUMEN THAL, THANK YOU
FOR BEING HERE.
NOT A PART OF PUBLIC SERVICE YOU
LOOK FORWARD TO.
>>> WHEN WE RETURN, A SURVIVOR
OF THE AURORA SHOOTING ON GUNS
AND GRIEVING.
TO THE BEST VACATION
SPOT ON EARTH.
(ALL) THE GULF!
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHICH OF
OUR GREAT STATES FOLKS VISIT.
MISSISSIPPI,
ALABAMA,
LOUISIANA
OR FLORIDA,
THEY'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
SHAUL, YOUR ALABAMA
HOSPITALITY IS INCREDIBLE.
THANKS, KAREN.
LOVE YOUR MISSISSIPPI OUTDOORS.
I VOTE FOR YOUR
FLORIDA BEACHES, DAWN.
BILL, THIS LOUISIANA
SEAFOOD IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR ON THE GULF,
WE'VE DECIDED TO PUT
ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
NOW IS THE PERFECT TIME TO
VISIT ANYONE OF OUR STATES.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE, GO FISHING
OR JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
WE'VE GOT COASTLINE TO EXPLORE
AND WILDLIFE TO PHOTOGRAPH.
AND THERE'S WORLD CLASS DINING
WITH OUR WORLD FAMOUS SEAFOOD.
SO FOR A GREAT VACATION
THIS YEAR, COME TO THE GULF.
ITS ALL FABULOUS BUT
I GIVE FLORIDA THE EDGE.
RIGHT AFTER MISSISSIPPI.
YOU MEAN ALABAMA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
THIS INVITATION IS
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP
AND ALL OF US WHO
CALL THE GULF HOME.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
>>> THOSE ARE LIVE PICTURES FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, IN FACT,
THIS SCENE, THE PEOPLE HAVE
CHANGED, BUT THE SCENE HAS NOT.
GETTING INTO THIS TOWN, GETTING
TO THE SITE OF WHERE SO MANY
VIGILS HAVE BEEN HELD, AND IT'S
A SMALL TOWN, THE TRAFFIC INTO
NEWTOWN HAS BEEN AMAZING.
THERE ARE MORE PEOPLE HERE THAN
ARE IN THE TOWN, CLEARLY THEY
ARE COMING FROM SO MANY PLACES
TO TRY TO KIND OF FIND A CENTRAL
POINT WHERE THEY LITERALLY CAN
COME TO SAY I'M SORRY, COME TO
SAY I FEEL THIS DISASTER THAT IT
WAS TO THE PEOPLE IN THE TOWN.
SO IT'S A KIND OF SCENE YOU SEE
EVERYWHERE AND HAVE SEEN
CONTINUALLY, MORNING AND EARLY
THIS MORNING WHEN WE DROVE IN
LATE LAST NIGHT AND EARLY THIS
MORNING, CARS BACKED UP JUST
TRYING TO GET INTO THIS TOWN.
SO THAT IS THE SCENE NOW AS WE
AWAIT, OF COURSE, THIS EVENING,
THE PRESIDENT WILL BE HERE AND
YOU WILL SEE EVEN LARGER CROWDS.
RIGHT NOW, I WANT TO INTRODUCE
YOU TO SOMEONE, STEVEN BARTON.
HE JUST WANTED TO SEE THE
MIDNIGHT PREMIER OF THE NEW
"BATMAN" MOVIE.
WHAT HAPPENED THAT NIGHT WAS
WORSE THAN ANY HORROR ON THE
SCREEN.
>> THIS PAST SUMMER IN A MOVIE
THEATER IN COLORADO, I WAS SHOT.
SHOT IN THE FACE AND NECK.
BUT I WAS LUCKY.
IN THE NEXT FOUR YEARS, 48,000
AMERICANS WON'T BE SO LUCKY.
BECAUSE THEY'LL BE MURDERED WITH
GUNS IN THE NEXT PRESIDENT'S
TERM.
ENOUGH TO FILL OVER 200
THEATERS.
>> STEVEN BARTON AS YOU MAY HAVE
FIGURED OUT IS WORKING FOR AN
ANTI-GUN GROUP, THE GROUP OF
MAYORS AGAINST ILLEGAL GUNS AND
JOINS ME NOW.
NICE TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
>> NICE TO SEE YOU.
>> WE MET EARLIER THIS YEAR WHEN
YOU WERE IN AT CNN IN
WASHINGTON.
WE'VE BEEN TALKING ABOUT GUN
CONTROL, BUT I WANT TO TALK TO
YOU AS SOMEONE WHO'S BEEN
THROUGH THIS EXPERIENCE AND WE
SHOULD TELL OUR VIEWERS YOU LIVE
TEN MINUTES FROM HERE.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> SO NOT ONLY WERE YOU AT THE
AURORA THEATER, HITCHHIKING
ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
>> BICYCLING.
>> BUT YOU LIVE TEN MINUTES FROM
HERE.
>> YES.
>> SO YOU MUST HAVE HAD SOME
REAL FLASHBACKS.
>> OH ABSOLUTELY.
AND BE EVEN NOW I'M DISCOVERING
PERSONAL CONNECTIONS TO THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, JUST PEOPLE I
KNOW WHO EITHER WERE WORKING
THERE, WHO KNEW PEOPLE WHO HAVE
BEEN KILLED, AND IT'S -- I NEVER
WOULD HAVE THOUGHT IN A THOUSAND
YEARS THAT THIS COMMUNITY, THIS
SMALL COMMUNITY, RIGHT DOWN THE
ROAD FROM WHERE I GREW UP WOULD
BE AFFECTED BY GUN VIOLENCE IN
THIS WAY.
>> TELL ME WHAT'S HELPED YOU?
>> HONESTLY MY FAMILY AND MY
FRIENDS.
YOU KNOW, I HAD A STRONG SUPPORT
SYSTEM, CONTINUE TO HAVE A
STRONG SUPPORT SYSTEM
SURROUNDING ME.
THEY'RE REALLY THERE TO TAKE
CARE OF YOU WHEN THINGS LIKE
THIS HAPPEN, FRANKLY.
>> AND THIS WAS ONLY IN JULY, SO
IT'S NOT AS THOUGH WE'RE TALKING
YEARS AGO.
>> YEAH.
>> WHAT DO YOU -- DO YOU STILL
WORK ON?
WHAT DO YOU STILL STRUGGLE WITH?
I ASK BECAUSE YOUR EXPERIENCE,
OBVIOUSLY, YOU KNOW, PEOPLE WHO
MIGHT NOT HAVE BEEN -- THE
FAMILIES OF THE KILLED, YOU
SURVIVED.
>> YES.
>> OBVIOUSLY AND SO THAT,
OBVIOUSLY, YOUR PARENTS KNOW
THAT YOU ARE HERE, BUT THERE ARE
NOW PARENTS AND SISTERS AND
BROTHERS AND, YOU KNOW, ALL OF
THAT STRUGGLING WITH THIS.
SO IT MIGHT BE HELPFUL, WHAT DO
YOU STRUGGLE WITH NOW AND DEAL
WITH THAT?
>> I JUST STRUGGLE TO SOMETIMES,
YOU KNOW, JUST FEEL SAFE
PUBLICLY.
YOU KNOW, AT THE MOVIES OR NOW I
GUESS AT SCHOOL, I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S A SLOW PROCESS OF HEALING
THAT YOU HAVE TO GO THROUGH AND
IT'S CONTINUOUS AND AT LEAST FOR
ME PERSONALLY IT'S GOING TO LAST
FOR A LONG TIME.
>> AND SO HOW OLD ARE YOU?
>> I'M 22 -- 23.
JUST TURNED 23.
>> MOVIE THEATERS, SCHOOLS, SEEM
LIKE SCARY PLACES?
>> IN SOME SENSE SOMETIMES, YES.
I'M SLOWLY COMING TO TERMS WITH
HA AND WORKING ON THAT, BUT FOR
A LONG TIME, I JUST DIDN'T WANT
TO BE NEAR A MOVIE THEATER.
>> YOUR WORK, I KNOW YOU DO THE
WORK WITH THE MAYOR'S GROUP THAT
WANTS TO BAN GUNS AND WORK FOR
SOME MORE GUN CONTROL.
>> YEAH.
>> DO YOU SENSE THAT THE TIME IS
NOW AND DIDN'T YOU SENSE THAT
MAYBE AFTER AURORA AS WELL?
>> I CERTAINLY HOPE SO AFTER
AURORA, THAT THE TIME IS RIGHT
FOR THIS CONVERSATION.
BUT I MEAN NOW --
>> BUT IT DIDN'T HAPPEN THEN.
I'M WONDERING IF YOU THINK --
>> WELL, GIVEN THE PRESIDENT'S
REMARKS, HE'S TALKED ABOUT THIS
BEFORE AFTER AURORA, AFTER
TUCSON, WE NEEDED A MEANINGFUL
CONVERSATION, BUT I THINK HIS
EMOTIONS REALLY REVEALED THE
EXTENT TO WHICH THIS HAS
AFFECTED HIM PERSONALLY AND
RIGHT NOW, WE NEED MORE THAN
ANYTHING ELSE, PRESIDENTIAL
LEADERSHIP ON THIS ISSUE.
SO I CAN'T BELIEVE THAT 20
CHILDREN WILL HAVE BEEN KILLED
IN VAIN AND NO CONVERSATION WILL
COME OUT OF THIS.
IT'S JUST TOO HORRIFYING, TOO
SHOCKING TO NOT PROVOKE SOME
DISCUSSION.
>> STEVEN BARTON, THANK YOU FOR
COMING BY.
>> THANK YOU.
>> APPRECIATE SEEING YOU AGAIN.
>> UP NEXT, FALSE REPORTS ABOUT
THE NEWTOWN SHOOTING CROPPING UP
ON SOCIAL MEDIA WEBSITES.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THEY ARE A GLOWING EXAMPLE
OF WHAT IT MEANS TO BE
THE BEST.
AND AT THIS SPECIAL TIME
OF YEAR,
THEY SHINE EVEN BRIGHTER.
COME TO THE WINTER EVENT
AND GET THE MERCEDES-BENZ
YOU'VE ALWAYS WISHED FOR,
NOW FOR AN EXCEPTIONAL PRICE.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
GLK350 FOR $399 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
Schwab Bank was built with all
the value and convenience
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
investors want.
Like no ATM fees, worldwide.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
And no nuisance fees.
Plus deposit checks with
Mobile Deposit.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
And manage your cash
and investments
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
with Schwab's mobile app.
No wonder Schwab Bank has grown
to over 70 billi in assets.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
So if you're looking for a bank
that's in your corner,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
not just on the corner...
Call, click or visit to start
banking with Schwab Bank today.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
PROGRESSIVE DIRECT AND OTHER
CAR INSURANCE COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
CALL OR CLICK TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN DIARRHEA HITS,
KAOPECTATE STOPS IT FAST.
POWERFUL LIQUID RELIEF
SPEEDS TO THE SOURCE.
FAST.
[ Male Announcer ]
STOP THE UH-OH FAST
WITH KAOPECTATE.
>>> AS WE HAVE REPORTED AT THE
TOP OF THE HOUR, CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE SAY THERE HAS BEEN
MISINFORMATION ABOUT THE
SHOOTING INVESTIGATION ON SOCIAL
MEDIA WEBSITES, INCLUDING CLAIMS
OF QUOTES FROM THE GUNMAN.
>> ONE THING THAT'S BECOMING
SOMEWHAT OF A CONCERN AND THAT
IS MISINFORMATION BEING POSTED
ON SOCIAL MEDIA SITES.
THERE HAS BEEN MISINFORMATION
COMING FROM PEOPLE POSING AS THE
SHOOTER IN THIS CASE, POSING
USING OTHER IDs, MIMICKING THIS
CRIME AND CRIME SCENE, AND CRIME
ACTIVITY THAT TOOK PLACE IN THIS
COMMUNITY.
>> I WANT TO BRING IN HOWARD
KURTZ, HE IS HOST OF CNN'S
"RELIABLE SOURCES."
I MEAN, YOU KNOW, IT'S A BRAVE
NEW WORLD OUT THERE AND I'M NOT
SURE HOW YOU CONTROL THIS PART
OF IT.
THIS IS SOCIAL MEDIA, YOU CAN GO
ANYWHERE, ANONYMOUSLY.
YOU CAN COVER YOUR FINGERPRINTS
AS IT WERE.
WHAT IS THE BEST WAY, DO YOU
THINK, TO GO ABOUT STOPPING THIS
SORT OF THING OR IS THERE NO
WAY?
>> YOU CAN'T STOP IT BECAUSE
SOCIAL MEDIA CAN BE A FORCE FOR
GOOD OR EVIL.
I WAS STUNNED, CANDY, TO HEAR
THE LIEUTENANT SAYING PEOPLE
WERE IMPERSONATING THE SHOOTER
ON FACEBOOK.
I PEEN IN THIS HORRIBLE
SITUATION THAT IS JUST TORN AT
THE HEARTSTRINGS OF THE COUNTRY,
IT SEEMS TO ME UNSPEAKABLY CRUEL
TO DO THIS KIND OF THING AND
YET, ALTHOUGH THE STATE POLICE
OFFICIAL SAID THAT SOMEBODY --
THAT PEOPLE MAY BE PROSECUTED
FOR THIS, DID A QUICK RESEARCH
AND IT'S NOT SO CLEAR.
YOU CAN BE PROSECUTED FOR CYBER
STALKING, DEFAMATION, MAKING
THREATS ON-LINE, HARASSING
PEOPLE ON-LINE OR CAUSING
SOMEONE REASONABLE DISTRESS.
I'M NOT SURE WHAT THE MOTIVE
WOULD BE OR HOW YOU COULD FRAME
ANY KIND OF INDICTMENT.
>> THE THING IS, THERE'S A LOT
OF UNSPEAKABLE CRUELTY THAT GOES
ON ON THE WEB.
WE HAVE CYBER BULLYING, PEOPLE
SAYING NASTY THINGS ABOUT, YOU
KNOW, ALL KINDS OF CIRCUMSTANCES
THAT WOULD REQUIRE I THINK A
MORE HUMANE APPROACH TO IT.
AND IN THE END IS THIS ONE OF
THOSE THINGS WHERE I SEE WE
COULD GO WITH, I DON'T KNOW,
CRYING FIRE IN A CROWDED
THEATER, THAT THERE'S SOME WAY
THE LAW COULD GO WITH THIS?
>> RIGHT.
I SUPPOSE IN EGREGIOUS CASES,
LAW ENFORCEMENT COULD FIND WAYS
TO PROSECUTE PEOPLE FOR USING
FALSE IDENTITIES.
LOTS OF PEOPLE, FOR EXAMPLE,
HAVE TWITTER SCREEN NAMES THAT
ARE NOT REAL.
THERE'S A CHALLENGE FOR
CONSUMERS OF THIS STUFF AND ALSO
A CHALLENGE FOR JOURNALISTS WHO
LIVE ON TWITTER THESE DAYS,
CONSULT FACEBOOK, NOT TO REPEAT
THIS INFORMATION EITHER ON-LINE
OR ON THE AIR, WITHOUT DOUBLE
CHECKING IT BECAUSE YOU CAN GET
IN A LOT OF TROUBLE TAKING IT ON
FAITH.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
AND I IMAGINE AT SOME LEVEL THIS
ALSO INTERFERES WITH THE
INVESTIGATION IF THEY'RE CHASING
DOWN RABBIT HOLES.
HOWIE KURTZ, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
"RELIABLE SOURCES."
WE WILL SEE YOU AGAIN SOON.
TO DANA BASH IN WASHINGTON, SHE
HAS A CHECK OF TOURTODAY'S HEAD.
>> A DEMOCRATIC SOURCE TELLS CNN
THE WHITE HOUSE BELIEVES THAT
JOHN BOEHNER, THE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER'S FIRST EVER OFFER TO
INCREASE TAX RATES ON THE
WEALTHIEST AMERICANS IS, QUOTE,
INSUFFICIENT.
THE WHITE HOUSE DOES THINK IT
REPRESENTS PROGRESS.
FRIDAY BOEHNER OFFERED TO RAISE
TAX RATES STARTING WITH INCOMES
OF $1 MILLION.
CNN IS ALSO TOLD IN RETURN,
BOEHNER ASKED FOR A SIGNIFICANT
SPENDING CUTS AND SOME SPECIFICS
LIKE RAISING THE ELIGIBILITY AGE
FOR MEDICARE.
>>> THE STATE DEPARTMENT IS
EXPECTED TO RECEIVE A HIGHLY
ANTICIPATED REPORT TOMORROW FROM
AN INDEPENDENT ADVISER REVIEW
BOARD WHICH HAS BEEN
INVESTIGATING WHAT WENT WRONG IN
SEPTEMBER'S DEADLY ATTACK IN
BENGHAZI.
CONGRESS WILL RECEIVE THE REPORT
AT A CLOSED HEARING ON
WEDNESDAY.
THE STATE DEPARTMENT IS ALSO
EXPECTED TO PRESENT
RECOMMENDATIONS ON IMPROVING
SECURITY AT U.S. EMBASSIES.
>>> SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON WILL NOT TESTIFY AT THIS
WEEK'S CONGRESSIONAL HEARINGS
ABOUT THAT BENGHAZI REPORT AS
ORIGINALLY PLANNED.
THAT'S BECAUSE SHE IS RECOVERING
FROM A CONCUSSION.
CLINTON SUSTAINED THE INJURY
AFTER SHE FAINTED DURING A BOUT
WITH A STOMACH FLU.
SHE'S MONER TOED BY DOCTORS WHO
RECOMMENDED SHE TAKE THE WEEK
OFF.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA APPEARS
READY TO NOMINATE SENATOR JOHN
KERRY AS HILLARY CLINTON'S
SUCCESSOR.
A DEMOCRAT WHO SPOKE WITH CNN
TELLS US THAT KERRY ANNOUNCEMENT
COULD COME AS EARLY AS THIS
WEEK.
KERRY IS THE CHAIRMAN OF THE
SENATE FOREIGN RELATIONS
COMMITTEE.
MANY OF HIS SENATE COLLEAGUES ON
BOTH SIDES OF THE AISLE HAVE
EXPRESSED SUPPORT FOR HIM AND
HE'S LIKELY TO EASILY WIN
CONFIRMATION AS SECRETARY OF
STATE.
BACK TO CANDY CROWLEY IN
NEWTOWN.
CANDY?
>> THANKS, DANA.
COMING UP, 20 YEARS AGO, SHE
LEARNED FIRSTHAND ABOUT GUN
VIOLENCE.
>> I CAME INTO CONGRESS BECAUSE
A TRAGEDY HAD HAPPENED TO MY
FAMILY AND TO OTHERS ON THE
RAILROAD, AND WHEN MY SON WAS
LEARNING HOW TO TALK AGAIN, YOU
KNOW, HE ASKED ME HOW THIS COULD
HAPPEN.
I DIDN'T HAVE THE ANSWER.
AND THAT'S WHEN I STARTED TO
LOOK INTO THE GUN VIOLENCE IN
THIS COUNTRY.
>> NOW, NEW YORK CONGRESSWOMAN
CAROLYN McCARTHY IS DETERMINED
TO MAKE SURE THE PRESIDENT
STANDS BEHIND HIS CALL FOR
MEANINGFUL CHANGE ON GUN
CONTROL.
T I'M STILL "STUBBED" U.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT DOESN'T HAVE A DECONGESTANT.
NO WAY.
[ Male Announcer ] SORRY.
Alka-Seltzer Plus FIGHTS
YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A FAST ACTING
DECONGESTANT
TO RELIEVE YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
[ sighs ] THANKS!
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus.
♪ OH
WHAT A RELIEF IT IS! ♪
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
AND SAVE $1
VISIT Alka-Seltzer ON FACEBOOK.
>>> SINCE THE MASSACRE AT
VIRGINIA TECH IN 2007, THERE
HAVE BEEN 19 OF WHAT THE FBI
CLASSIFIES AS MASS SHOOTINGS IN
THE UNITED STATES.
WHAT THERE HASN'T BEEN IS WHAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS NOW CALLING
FOR, MEANINGFUL CHANGE IN THE
GUN LAWS.
JOINING ME NOW IS NEW YORK
CONGRESSWOMAN CAROLYN McCARTHY.
CONGRESSWOMAN McCARTHY, THANK
YOU SO MUCH.
I MUST SAY WHEN I LISTENED TO
THE PRESIDENT ON FRIDAY, I
BELIEVE IT WAS, I DIDN'T HEAR
HIM TALK ABOUT NEW LAWS.
I HEARD HIM TALK ABOUT
MEANINGFULLY CHANGE.
DO YOU THINK, HAVE YOU TALKED TO
THE PRESIDENT, AND DO YOU THINK
HE WILL NOW PUSH WHAT YOU'RE
WANTING TO DO, VIS-A-VIS GUN
LAWS?
>> WELL, TO BE VERY HONEST WITH
YOU, I KNOW THAT THE PRESIDENT
COULD BE TALKING FROM THE BULLY
PULPIT.
CERTAINLY WE CAN HOPEFULLY WORK
TOGETHER ON PASSING SOME
LEGISLATION THAT IS CERTAINLY
BEEN INTRODUCED EVERY YEAR.
BUT WHAT THE PRESIDENT CAN DO IS
AN EXECUTIVE ORDER TO TIGHTEN UP
SOME OF THE LAWS THAT ARE STILL
ALREADY OUT THERE.
"THE NEW YORK TIMES" RELEASED A
REPORT YESTERDAY AND THIS
MORNING THAT BASICALLY WAS
TALKING ABOUT A BILL THAT WAS
PASSED IN 2008, RIGHT AFTER
VIRGINIA TECH, THAT WAS A BILL
THAT I GOT PASSED THROUGH THE
HOUSE, THROUGH THE SENATE, AND
PRESIDENT BUSH SIGNED THAT, BUT
THE PROBLEM WITH THAT IS THAT
THERE HAS NEVER BEEN ENOUGH
MONEY THERE TO HAVE ALL THE
COURTS -- ANYBODY THAT'S BEEN
ADJUDICATED THROUGH THE COURTS
WHETHER FOR ANY CRIME THAT WOULD
ALREADY BASICALLY NOT ALLOW
SOMEONE TO OWN A GUN, TO BE PUT
INTO THE INSTANT BACKGROUND
SYSTEM.
THAT'S SOMETHING HE CAN DO.
THE HEAVY LIFTING IS GOING TO
HAVE TO COME FROM CONGRESS AND
IT WILL, BUT IF HE IS WILLING TO
USE THE BULLY PULPIT, HE CAN
ACTUALLY HELP US.
PRESIDENT CLINTON DID THAT.
IT WAS A TOUGH STRUGGLE BUT HE
GOT IT THROUGH.
FOR SOME REASON, AND I
PERSONALLY FEEL BECAUSE IT WAS
SO MANY CHILDREN INVOLVED, THE
ATTITUDES OF THE AMERICAN PEOPLE
ARE LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT THAN
THEY WERE BEFORE FRIDAY.
>> SO, BY IT, I BELIEVE YOU MEAN
AN ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN, IS THAT
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT, THE
PRESIDENT WOULD GET BEHIND THAT,
WHICH EXPIRED PROBABLY MORE THAN
TEN YEARS AGO?
>> YEAH.
THAT EXPIRED IN THE YEAR 2004.
I KNOW SENATOR FEINSTEIN HAS
BEEN WORKING ON A NEW ASSAULT
WEAPONS BILL.
SHE'S BEEN WORKING ON IT FOR A
WHILE.
>> RIGHT.
>> WITH THE INTENTION OF MOST
LIKELY INTRODUCING IT OVER THE
FIRST OF THE YEAR WHEN WE GO
INTO A NEW SESSION.
AND WE'RE GOING TO BE WORKING
WITH HER ON THAT.
BUT THE 208 BILL THAT WAS
PASSED, IS THE NIC IMPROVEMENT
ACT.
THAT GOES TO THE COURTS BECAUSE
WE FOUND WHEN PEOPLE WERE
ADJUDICATED TO BE MENTALLY ILL,
AND THAT HAPPENED WITH THE
VIRGINIA TECH SHOOTING, THAT THE
RECORDS NEVER WENT INTO THE
INSTANT BACKGROUND CHECK.
IT WOULD COVER ANYONE DOMESTIC
VIOLENCE, FELONIES, HE COULD DO
SOMETHING BIG ON THAT RIGHT
AWAY.
AND THEN LIKE I SAID, WE WOULD
HAVE TO WORK TOGETHER.
>> RIGHT.
AND AS -- IN FACT, SENATOR
FEINSTEIN SAID THIS MORNING SHE
WOULD INTRODUCE AN ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN BILL AND TRY TO CUT
DOWN ON SOME OF THE LARGE
CAPACITY MAGAZINES THAT CAN
SHOOT 30, 40, 100 ROUNDS OF
AMMUNITION IN 30 SECONDS OR
SOMETHING, BUT LET ME GO BACK,
BECAUSE YOU'RE RIGHT, THE
VIRGINIA TECH SHOOTER DID, IN
FACT, HAVE A MENTAL HEALTH
HISTORY THAT HAD HE BEEN BE IN
THE RECORDS, IT MIGHT HAVE
HALTED HIM FROM GETTING THE
GUNS, BUT THERE HAVE BEEN OTHER
CASES -- IN TUCSON, FOR
INSTANCE, AND SO FAR AS WE KNOW
AT LEAST IN THIS CASE, THERE'S
NO MENTAL HEALTH BACKGROUND.
IN THE END, THAT MIGHT HELP, BUT
IT MIGHT NOT HAVE PREVENTED
THIS.
AND IT MIGHT NOT HAVE PREVENTED
WHAT WENT ON IN TUCSON.
WITH THAT IN MIND, I WANTED TO
PLAY YOU SOMETHING THAT THE
FORMER EDUCATION SECRETARY BILL
BENNETT SAID THIS MORNING
TALKING ABOUT SECURITY AROUND
SCHOOLS.
>> I'M NOT SO SURE I WOULDN'T
WANT ONE PERSON IN A SCHOOL
ARMED, READY FOR THIS KIND OF
THING.
THE PRINCIPAL LUNGED AT THIS
GUY.
THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST LUNGED
AT THE GUY.
HAS TO BE SOMEONE WHO'S TRAINED,
WHO'S RESPONSIBLE, BUT MY GOD,
IF YOU CAN PREVENT THIS KIND OF
THING.
>> SO, CONGRESSWOMAN, WHAT ABOUT
THAT BECAUSE THAT'S THE PUSH
FROM THE OTHER SIDE, THAT THEY
WERE JUST COMPLETELY DEFENSELESS
INSIDE THIS SCHOOL.
WHAT WOULD YOU THINK ABOUT
SOMETHING LIKE THAT BILL BENNETT
IS TALKING ABOUT?
>> WELL, TO BE VERY HONEST WITH
YOU, GOING BACK AGAIN AFTER THE
VIRGINIA TECH LEGISLATION WAS
PUT INTO LEAVE NO CHILD BEHIND
WHICH BASICALLY I AUTHORED AND
THAT WAS TO PREPARE THE
SCHOOLS -- AND BY THE WAY THE
SCHOOL OF CONNECTICUT DID
EVERYTHING RIGHT AND THEY DID.
THEY HAD THE LOCKDOWN.
BUT PEOPLE HAVE TO UNDERSTAND WE
CANNOT SAVE EVERY LIFE.
THERE'S NO LAW THAT COULD DO
THAT.
AND AS FAR AS HAVING MORE GUNS,
WE HAVE MORE GUNS IN THIS
COUNTRY THAN ANY OTHER CIVILIZED
NATION.
IT HAS TO BE LOOKED AT
WHOLISTICALLY.
WE HAVE TO LOOK AT MENTAL
HEALTH, WE HAVE TO LOOK AT THOSE
SIGNS THAT LED UP TO THE OTHER
SHOOTINGS AND NOW WE'RE SEEING
THAT PEOPLE TALKING ABOUT THIS
PARTICULAR SHOOTER ALSO HAD
SIGNS.
SO I MEAN IT'S A COMBINATION OF
THINGS THAT WE CAN DO ON THE
SOCIAL LEVEL, WE CAN ASK PEOPLE,
CERTAINLY CHILDREN HAVE BEEN
TRAINED, ESPECIALLY GH SCHOOL
KIDS, YOU KNOW, IF YOU SEE A
CLASSMATE THAT IS ACTING STRANGE
OR TEACHERS SEEING SOMEONE THAT
MIGHT BE ANTI-SOCIAL, TO MAKE
SURE THAT YOUNG PERSON GETS SOME
HELP.
WE DON'T HAVE THE ANSWER FOR
EVERY SINGLE SITUATION.
THAT SHOULD NOT PREVENT US FOR
THE BIGGER PICTURE WHEN YOU LOOK
AT AN AWFUL LOT OF THESE KILLERS
THAT WERE MENTALLY ILL, THE
SIGNS WERE THERE, BUT
UNFORTUNATELY NOBODY PICKED UP
FOR THEM.
SantHo, Ho, Ho!anta!
Santa!
Want to see some magic?
Watch this! Merry Chr...
(Crash) Ow!
I landed on my keys.
Did you get that?
Oh yeah.
That was amazing.
Here you go.
That was a fun trick!
See? Santa's okay.
Walk it off Santa.
Share videos instantly
with S Beam.
On the Galaxy SIII
and Note II.
For a limited time get two flip
covers for the price of one.
Exclusively at Verizon.
WE DON'T LET FREQUENT HEARTBURN
COME BETWEEN US
AND WHAT WE LOVE.
SO IF YOU'RE ONE OF THEM PEOPLE
WHO GETS HEARTBURN
AND THEN TREATS DAY AFTER DAY...
BLOCK THE ACID WITH PRILOSEC OTC
AND DON'T GET HEARTBURN
IN THE FIRST PLACE!
[ Male Announcer ]
ONE PILL EACH MORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBURN.
HOW MUCH IS
YOUR CURRENT PHONE BILL?
FOUR SIXTEEN SEVENTY SIX
A MONTH!
OKAY, COME WITH ME --
WE'RE GONNA SAVE YOU MONEY.
WITH STRAIGHT TALK
AT WALMART,
YOU GET UNLIMITED TALK,
TEXT AND DATA
FOR ONLY $45 A MONTH
PER PHONE.
WOULD WE GET
THE SAME COVERAGE?
SAME COVERAGE
ON AMERICA'S BEST NETWORKS.
YOU SAVED $146.76
BY SWITCHING TO STRAIGHT TALK.
AWESOME!
NOW YOU CAN AFFORD
TO SHARE YOUR ALLOWANCE
WITH ME.
GET THE SEASON'S
HOTTEST SMARTPHONES
LIKE THE SAMSUNG GALAXY S2
AND GET STRAIGHT TALK
WITH UNLIMITED DATA
FOR JUST $45 A MONTH --
FROM AMERICA'S
GIFT HEADQUARTERS. WALMART.
♪
>>> YOU ARE LOOKING AT SOME LIVE
PICTURES OF DOWNTOWN, IF THERE
IS SUCH A THING IN A TOWN SUCH
AS THIS, NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
BALLOONS, TEDDY BEARS, NOTES
THAT WOULD BREAK YOUR HEART.
FLOWERS, ANYTHING YOU CAN
IMAGINE THAT PEOPLE COULD BRING.
MIXED IN WITH CHRISTMAS
DECORATIONS.
THERE IS THIS DISSONANCE HERE
WITH THIS SEASON OF JOY AND
THESE HORRIFIC MASS KILLINGS OF
20 CHILDREN, ADULTS, INSIDE THAT
SCHOOL.
IT MAKES THE MIX, JUST
HEARTBREAKING.
THIS HAS GONE ON SINCE THE DAY,
REALLY, OF THOSE KILLINGS, TO
GET INTO NEWTOWN AT THIS POINT,
IS QUITE A FEAT.
WE HAVE HAD SOME GUESTS COMING
TO THIS EDITION OF "STATE OF THE
UNION" THAT GOT OUT AND WALKED
BECAUSE THE TRAFFIC COMING INTO
THIS TOWN, PEOPLE WANTING TO DO
ANYTHING, BRING SOMETHING TO SAY
TO THE PEOPLE OF THIS FLATTENED
TOWN, WE CARE, WE KNOW YOU'RE
SUFFERING.
OF COURSE TONIGHT THE PRESIDENT
IS GOING TO BE HERE AND KIND OF
SPEAK FOR THE NATION OF THE
GRIEF THAT SO MANY PEOPLE FEEL
THAT ARE NOT DIRECTLY CONNECTED
TO THIS TRAGEDY.
AND THE INVESTIGATION, IT GOES
ON AS FAR AS WE KNOW AND AS FAR
AS WE WERE TOLD JUST AN HOUR
AGO, IN FACT, THEY ARE STILL IN
THE SCHOOL, THEY ARE STILL AT
VARIOUS SITES IN THIS
INVESTIGATION.
I SPOKE WITH CONNECTICUT'S
GOVERNOR EARLIER THIS MORNING.
>> GOVERNOR, THANK YOU FOR
JOINING US HERE.
LET ME JUST FIRST ASK YOU ABOUT
THE STATE OF THE INVESTIGATION.
WHAT DO WE NOW KNOW AND WHERE
ARE WE IN THE INVESTIGATION?
>> YOU KNOW, FIRST AND FOREMOST,
THAT'S A STATE POLICE IS
HANDLING THAT INVESTIGATION.
I THINK WE KNOW EVERYTHING THAT
IS MOST IMPORTANT.
THERE WAS A SINGLE SHOOTER AND
THAT SHOOTER IS DEAD.
HE WAS TROUBLED INDIVIDUAL AND
HE WENT TO THE SCHOOL WITH A
NUMBER OF WEAPONS, WHICH HE USED
ON HIS VICTIMS AND ULTIMATELY
USED ON HIMSELF.
YOU KNOW, SOME OF THIS OTHER
STUFF WILL PLAY OUT OVER A
PERIOD OF TIME.
I'M SURE WE'LL COME TO KNOW MORE
ABOUT HIM, HIS PROBLEMS, AND HIS
FAMILY.
YOU KNOW, THESE THINGS MOVE ON.
THIS INVESTIGATION WILL TELL US
THOSE THINGS, BUT, YOU KNOW, I
DON'T HAVE A WHOLE LOT MORE THAN
THAT.
>> SO TELL ME, LET ME GO BACK TO
A COUPLE THINGS YOU JUST SAID.
THE FIRST IS THE WEAPONRY.
SO FAR AS YOU KNOW, WERE THESE
WEAPONS LEGALLY OBTAINED BY THE
MOTHER, WHICH WE'RE LED TO
BELIEVE THEY WERE HER WEAPONS?
>> THE MOTHER PURCHASED THEM.
THEY HAVE THE PATINA OF LEGAL
PURCHASES.
THERE'S ALWAYS A QUESTION WAS
SHE PURCHASING THEM FOR HERSELF,
WHICH IN THAT CASE IT WAS LEGAL.
IF SHE WAS PURCHASING THEM FOR
ANOTHER INDIVIDUAL, HER SON,
THEN THERE'S A QUESTION ABOUT
THAT PURCHASE.
>> DO WE KNOW ANYTHING THAT
INDICATES THAT?
>> THE OTHER THING IS THIS
ASSAULT WEAPON.
CONNECTICUT HAS A PRETTY
AGGRESSIVE LAW PROBABLY OF THE
50 STATES, WE'RE RANKED FOURTH
MOST AGGRESSIVE IN TRYING TO
LIMIT ACCESS TO THESE KINDS OF
WEAPONS.
WHAT HAPPENS IN THE ABSENCE OF A
BRADY BILL, IN THE ABSENCE OF
FEDERAL LEGISLATION, PEOPLE USE
DESCRIPTIVE TERMS TO TRY TO GET
AROUND THE LIMITATIONS THAT ARE
BUILT INTO OUR STATUTES HERE IN
CONNECTICUT OR MIGHT OTHERWISE
NOT HAPPEN IF WE HAD FEDERAL
LEGISLATION ON THIS ISSUE.
THESE ARE ASSAULT WEAPONS.
YOU DON'T HUNT DEER WITH THESE
THINGS.
I THINK THAT'S THE QUESTION THAT
A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE GOING TO
HAVE TO RESOLVE THEIR OWN MINDS.
WHERE SHOULD THIS LINE GET
DRAWN?
>> SO AS I UNDERSTAND WHAT
YOU'RE SAYING, THERE WAS A SEMI
ASSAULT WEAPON BUT NOT
NECESSARILY ONE BANNED BY
CONNECTICUT, WHICH HAS A STATE
LAW BANNING CERTAIN KINDS OF
ASSAULT WEAPONS?
>> WELL, BUT THAT THEN BEGS THE
QUESTION, WAS THIS A WEAPON THAT
SHOULD HAVE BEEN BANNED AND
BECAUSE OF HOW
THE MANUFACTURER DECIDED TO
DESCRIBE IT GOT AROUND THAT LAW?
>> SO LET ME GO BACK TO A COUPLE
THINGS THAT YOU SAID.
THE FIRST IS, IS THERE ANYTHING
THAT LEADS YOU TO BELIEVE SHE
MIGHT HAVE PURCHASED THEM FOR
HER SON, OR IS THAT JUST HERE
ARE THE POSSIBILITIES?
>> HERE ARE THE POSSIBILITIES.
THEY'RE LIVING TOGETHER.
THEY'RE IN THE HOME.
HE ENDS UP WITH THE GUNS, SO
THERE MAY BE AN EXPLANATION.
>> THEY'RE LOOKING INTO THAT.
THE OTHER ISSUE DESCRIBED HIS AS
TROUBLED, WHICH WE KNOW FROM
WHAT HE DID.
IS THERE OTHER EVIDENCE AS
THEY'VE GONE IN ABOUT TROUBLED
HOW?
>> YOU KNOW, CLEARLY, HE WAS
TROUBLED.
YOU HAVE TO BE DERANGED TO CARRY
OUT THIS KIND OF CRIME.
YOU KNOW, I'M NOT IN A POSITION
THAT I SHOULD BE TALKING ABOUT
ABOUT SOMEONE ELSE'S FAMILY.
THAT INFORMATION WILL COME OUT
IN DUE COURSE, BUT THIS WAS
CLEARLY A TROUBLED PERSON.
>> IS THERE EVIDENCE THAT HE WAS
MENTALLY DISABLED IN SOME WAY?
>> THERE'S EVIDENCE THAT HE WAS
MENTALLY DISABLED BY THE ACTS
THAT HE COMMITTED.
ONE DOESN'T SHOOT THEIR
MOTHER --
>> SURE.
BUT NOTHING BEHIND THAT YOU'RE
FINDING IN THE INVESTIGATION
THUS FAR?
>> THERE ARE -- AS HAS BEEN
ATTESTED TO ALREADY BY FAMILY
MEMBERS AND OTHERS IN THE
NEWSPAPERS, THIS WAS A TROUBLED
INDIVIDUAL.
>> OKAY.
AS FAR AS THE GUNS ARE
CONCERNED, DO THEY COME OUT OF
THE HOME?
IS THAT WHERE THEY -- WERE THEY
SECURED IN THE HOME?
>> YES, THAT'S OUR BELIEF.
>> LET ME MOVE YOU ON TO YOUR
ROLE NOW.
THERE ALWAYS COMES THIS POINT
WHERE THE INVESTIGATION IS
ONGOING.
THIS INCREDIBLE GRIEF THESE
FAMILIES MUST BE AND ARE
SUFFERING IS GOING ON.
WHAT DO YOU DO NOW?
>> YOU KNOW, CANDY, I WAS WITH
THE VAST MAJORITY OF THE
FAMILIES FRIDAY MORNING, AND
ULTIMATELY I HAD TO BREAK IT TO
ALL OF THE FOLKS WHO WERE
ASSEMBLED AT THE FIREHOUSE THAT
THEIR CHILDREN OR LOVED ONE IN
THE CASE OF THE ADULTS WERE NOT
COMING HOME.
AND THAT'S AN EXERCISE THAT I
WILL LIVE WITH FOR THE REST OF
MY LIFE.
IT'S NOT SOMETHING YOU'RE
PREPARED FOR, AND YOU GO ON.
BUT, YOU KNOW, LISTEN, I'M THE
GOVERNOR OF THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT.
WE HAVE A JOB TO DO.
WE HAVE TO PROTECT PEOPLE AND
HELP PEOPLE RECOVER AND MOVE ON
AND GET CHILDREN BACK TO SCHOOL
AS QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE IN THE
BROADER SYSTEM AND HOPEFULLY
THESE CHILDREN AT THIS SCHOOL
BACK TO SCHOOL -- A SCHOOL AS
QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE.
>> TO MAKE SURE I UNDERSTOOD YOU
CORRECTLY.
YOU'RE THE ONE THAT INITIALLY
HAD TO TELL THE FAMILIES
GATHERED IN THAT ROOM WHAT MANY
FEARED OR SINCE SOME OF THEM
MIGHT HAVE ALREADY KNOWN AT A
GUT LEVEL, YOU WERE THE ONE THAT
FINALIZED IT FOR THEM?
>> YES.
>> TELL ME ABOUT THAT MOMENT.
>> IT'S A VERY DIFFICULT THING
TO DO.
THESE PARENTS HAD BEEN GATHERED
FOR A NUMBER OF HOURS CLINGING
TO HOPE.
NEWS REPORTS WERE SWIRLING
AROUND THEM OUTSIDE THE
BUILDING.
SOMEONE HAD TO DECIDE HOW TO
HANDLE THAT SITUATION.
ULTIMATELY IT FELL UPON ME TO DO
THAT.
YOU KNOW, YOU CAN NEVER BE
PREPARED FOR THAT, TO TELL 18 OR
20 FOLKS OR ACTUALLY FAMILIES
THAT THEIR LOVED ONE WOULD NOT
BE RETURNING TO THEM THAT DAY OR
IN THE FUTURE IT IS A TOUGH
ASSIGNMENT.
>> GOVERNOR, I WANT TO THANK YOU
FOR YOUR TIME THIS MORNING.
>> THANK YOU.
>> UP NEXT, REACHING OUT FROM
THE OVAL OFFICE TO HELP A NATION
MOURN.
THEY'VE BEEN COMMITTED
TO PUTTING CLIENTS FIRST.
HELPING GENERATIONS
THROUGH TOUGH TIMES.
GOOD TIMES.
NEVER TAKING A BAILOUT.
THERE WHEN YOU NEED THEM.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
OVER THE CENTURIES.
THE STRENGTH OF
A GLOBAL FINANCIAL LEADER.
THE HEART OF
A ONE-TO-ONE RELATIONSHIP.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
>>> THIS EVENING THE PRESIDENT
WILL BE IN NEWTOWN TO MEET
PRIVATELY WITH FAMILIES OF THE
VICTIMS AND SPEAK AT A PUBLIC
INTERFAITH VIGIL.
THE NEED FOR A PRESIDENT TO PUT
WORDS TO A COLLECTIVE GRIEF IS A
FAMILIAR PART OF THE RHYTHM OF
TRAGEDIES THAT TEAR OPEN THE
SOUL OF THIS NATION.
>> "CHALLENGER" NOW HEADING
DOWNRANGE.
>> THE CREW OF THE SPACE SHUTTLE
"CHALLENGER" HONORED FOR THE
MANNER IN WHICH THEY LIVED THEIR
LIVES, WE WILL NEVER FORGET THEM
NOR THE LAST TIME WE SAW THEM
THIS MORNING, AS THEY PREPARED
FOR THEIR JOURNEY AND WAVED
GOOD-BYE.
>> WHEN THERE IS TALK OF HATRED,
LET US STAND UP AND TALK AGAINST
IT.
WHEN THERE IS TALK OF VIOLENCE,
LET US STAND UP AND TALK AGAINST
IT.
IN THE FACE OF DEATH, LET US
HONOR LIFE.
YOU GOT TO HELP US HERE.
TAKE CARE OF YOURSELVES AND YOUR
FAMILIES FIRST.
TAKE CARE OF THE SCHOOL NEXT.
BUT REMEMBER YOU CAN HELP
AMERICA HEAL AND IN SO DOING YOU
WILL SPEED THE PROCESS OF
HEALING FOR YOURSELVES.
>> THE PICTURES OF AIRPLANES
FLYING INTO BUILDINGS, FIRES
BURNING, HUGE STRUCTURES
COLLAPSING, HAVE FILLED US WITH
DI