>>> THAT DOES IT HERE FOR US
TONIGHT IN NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT.
WE NOW WANT TO BRING YOU THE
VIGIL IN ITS ENTIRETY.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> ON BEHALF OF THE NEWTOWN
INTERFAITH CLERGY ASSOCIATION I
WELCOME ALL OF YOU.
WE NEEDED THIS.
WE NEEDED TO BE TOGETHER HERE IN
THIS ROOM IN THE GYMNASIUM,
OUTSIDE THE DOORS OF THIS SCHOOL
IN LIVING ROOMS AROUND THE
WORLD.
WE NEEDED TO BE TOGETHER.
TO SHOW THAT WE ARE TOGETHER AND
UNITED.
WE GATHER IN SUCH A MOMENT OF
HEARTBREAK FOR ALL OF US HERE IN
NEW TOWN.
WE GATHER ESPECIALLY MINDFUL OF
FAMILY AND FRIENDS.
AND NEIGHBORS AMONG US WHO HAVE
LOST LOVED ONES BY AN ACT OF
UNFATHOMABLE VIOLENCE AND
DESTRUCTION WE GATHER TO GRIEVE
TOGETHER, CARE FOR ONE ANOTHER,
PRAY AND EMBRACE, TO WEEP AND TO
REMEMBER AND TO DECLARE IN OUR
MANY VOICES THAT THESE DARKEST
DAYS OF OUR COMMUNITY SHALL NOT
BE THE FINAL WORD HEARD FROM US.
WE WILL SIGH IN OUR SORROWS, BUT
WE WILL ALSO CARE FOR ONE
ANOTHER WITH OUR LOVE AND OUR
COMPASSION.
IN THOSE EARLY HOURS OF THIS
CRISIS, IT BECAME CLEAR TO US
CLERGY AND FAITH LEADERS HERE IN
NEWTOWN THAT AN INITIAL
COMMUNITY RESPONSE WOULD BE
NEEDED, THAT WE WOULD NEED TO
COME TOGETHER AND SO WE ASKED
OUR FIRST SELECT WOMAN AND OUR
SUPERINTENDENT IF IT MIGHT BE
POSSIBLE FOR US TO INVITE THE
COMMUNITY TO GATHER HERE AT NEW
TOWN HIGH SCHOOL TO CONTINUE AND
TO BEGIN AND CONTINUE WHAT WILL
BE FOR MANY A LONG JOURNEY OF
GRIEF AND LOSS.
WE ARE NOT HERE TO IGNORE OUR
DIFFERENCES OR DIMINISH THE CORE
BELIEFS WHICH DEFINE OUR MANY
DIFFERENT FAITH TRADITIONS, BUT
TO OFFER OUR LOVE, CARE AND
PRAYERS FOR OUR FAMILYIES AND
OTHER COMMUNITY.
WE WANTED TO OFFER OUR VOICES IN
THE FORM OF WORDS FROM OUR
SACRED TEXTS AND PRAYERS FROM
THE DEPTHS OF OUR BEING.
BUT ALSO TO HAVE TIME FOR US TO
BE TOGETHER IN SILENCE.
AND THAT IS WHAT WE WILL DO.
WE WILL HAVE A TIME FOR SHARING
AND PRAYER, AND ALSO A TIME FOR
SILENCE IN BETWEEN.
SO IN A ALL OF US CAN PRAY IF WE
WISH AND THINK ABOUT WHAT IT IS
THAT IS MOST IMPORTANT TO US.
NOW, THERE IS A REASON WHY ALL
THE CLERGY ARE SITTING DOWN
THERE INSTEAD OF UP HERE.
WE WANTED TO BE -- TO HAVE A
SYMBOLIC GESTURE THAT WE
OURSELVES ARE WITH YOU AND AMONG
YOU IN THESE COMING DAYS.
THAT WE ARE ALL IN THIS
TOGETHER.
WE WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT OUR
CARE FOR THIS COMMUNITY EXTENDS
BEYOND THE WALLS OF OUR VARIOUS
HOUSES OF WORSHIP AND THE PEOPLE
WITHIN THEM.
WE ARE HERE FOR ALL OF NEWTOWN.
THAT MEANS THAT YOU, WHO ARE OF
ST. ROSE CATHOLIC CHURCH, IN THE
MIDST OF YOUR TREMENDOUS GRIEF,
THERE IS A JEWISH RABBI WITH A
TORAH IN HAND READY TO SPEAK
WORDS OF COMFORT AND DO WHATEVER
HE CAN TO UPHOLD YOU IN THE
COMING DAYS.
AND TEMPLE ISRAEL, YOU HAVE THE
SERVICE OF A JAPANESE AMERICAN
UNITED METHODIST MINISTER READY
TO PRAY WITH YOU AND SHARE SONGS
FROM JOHN WESLEY.
WE UCC-ERS KNOW WITH HAVE
MUSLIMS READY TO PRAY WITH US.
AND LUTHERANS OFFERING MINISTRY
OF GRACE IN JESUS CHRIST AND TO
CHRISTIANS AND OTHERS.
ALL OF US WILLING TO RECEIVE
COMFORT AND SUPPORT FROM THOSE
OF NO FAITH, YOU SEE, NOW MORE
THAN EVER WE NEED EACH OTHER FOR
WE ARE ALL IN THIS TOGETHER.
THAT'S WHY WE EVEN HAVE OUR
POLITICIANS SIT DOWN THERE AS
WELL.
A SIGN AND SYMBOL TO ALL OF US
THAT WE ARE IN THIS TOGETHER.
NOW, LET'S COME TOGETHER, LET US
PRAY, LET US LISTEN AND LET US
SEEK THE COMFORT OF OUR VARIOUS
FAITHS, DRAWING FROM WORDS AND
FROM PRAYERS.
FEAR NOT FOR I AM WITH YOU.
BE NOT DISMAYED, FOR I AM YOUR
GOD.
I WILL STRENGTHEN YOU, I WILL
UPHOLD YOU WITH MY VICTORIOUS
HAND.
GOD IS WITH US.
GOD'S LOVE UNITES US, GOD'S
PURPOSE STEADIES US.
GOD'S SPIRIT COMFORTS US.
BLESS BE OUR GOD FOREVER AND
EVER.
AMEN.
>> I OFFER YOU THIS PRAYER FROM
MY HEART TO YOUR HEARTS.
ON BEHALF OF ALL OF YOUR
CHILDREN, ALL OF YOUR LOVED
ONES.
THE HEBREW MEMORIAL PRAYER.
PLEASE RISE.
♪
>> OH, GOD EXALTED IN FULL OF
COMPASSION, GRANT PERFECT PEACE
IN YOUR SHELTERING PRESENCE
AMONG THE HOLY AND THE PURE TO
THE SOULS OF ALL OF OUR LOVED
ONES THAT PERISHED IN THAT
HORRIBLE DAY.
THEY HAVE GONE TO THEIR ETERNAL
HOME, MASTER OF MERCY, WE
BESEECH YOU.
REMEMBER ALL OF THEIR WORTHY AND
RIGHTEOUS DEEDS THAT THEY
PERFORMED IN THE LAND OF THE
LIVING.
MAY THEIR SOULS BE BOUND UP IN
THE BOND OF LIFE ETERNAL.
THERE IS NO DEATH, JUST
TRANSFORMATION.
MAY THEY REST IN PEACE.
AND LET US SAY AMEN.
>> AMEN.
>> PLEASE, BE SEATED.
AND LET US UNITE OUR HEARTS IN
PRAYER.
OH, GOD OF LOVE AND MERCY.
WE COME BEFORE YOU THIS NIGHT
WITH BROKEN HEARTS.
WE OFFER YOU OUR TEARS AND OUR
PAIN, OUR ANGER AND OUR SORROW.
OH, LORD, THERE WAS A HOLE SO
LARGE WE WONDER IF EVEN YOU AND
YOUR GREATNESS CAN FILL IT AS WE
GRIEVE AND MOURN FOR THOSE WHO
ARE LOST.
EACH LIGHT THAT SITS BEFORE US
IS A LIGHT THAT'S BEEN LOST TO
OUR WORLD.
SO MANY INNOCENTS, SO MANY
BRAVE.
LORD, ALL WE CAN DO IS THROW
OURSELVES UPON YOUR TENDER
MERCIES, TRUSTING THAT YOU HEAR
OUR PRAYERS.
WE KNOW THOSE WHO ARE LOST,
BECAUSE THEY ARE OURS, LORD.
NOT NAMES ON SOME LIST, BUT OUR
MOTHERS OR SISTERS, OUR BROTHERS
OR FRIENDS, KINDRED ALL, BECAUSE
IF WE DID NOT KNOW THEM
OURSELVES, WE KNOW SOMEONE WHO
DID.
AND SO WE PRAY, LORD, FOR ALL
THE SOULS LOST AND ALL THE
FAMILIES AND FRIENDS WHO ARE SO
TORN BY GRIEF.
FOR IN THIS MOMENT, WE ARE ALL
YOUR CHILDREN, A FAMILY RELATED
BY YOUR LOVE.
SO HELP US TO CARE FOR THESE
FAMILIES IN THEIR SORROW AND FOR
EACH OTHER IN OURS.
MAY THEY FEEL THE HEALING
EMBRACE OF A NEIGHBORHOOD, A
TOWN, A STATE, A NATION, A
WORLD.
HELP US TO FOREVER REMEMBER THAT
WE EMBRACE THE GRIEVING AS OUR
OWN AND BRING US TOGETHER AS ONE
FAMILY TO LIVE TOGETHER IN PEACE
AND AMITY.
HELP US TO SHARE THE LIGHTS THAT
STAND BEFORE US.
HELP US TO CARRY THEM OUT INTO
THIS WORLD AND SHARE IT WITH A
WORLD SO IN SORROW AND SO IN
NEED.
FOR WE PRAY ALL OF THIS IN THE
NAME OF YOUR LOVE AS WE ALL SAY
AMEN.
>> WE INVITE YOU TO JOIN WITH US
IN PSALM 23 IN WHATEVER WAY YOU
KNOW IT IN YOUR HEART.
DOESN'T HAVE TO BE THE WORDS
WE'RE OFFERING HERE.
THE LORD IS MY SHEPHERD, I SHALL
NOT WANT.
HE MAKETH ME TO LIE DOWN IN
GREEN PASTURES.
HE LEADETH ME BESIDE THE STILL
WATERS.
HE RESTORETH MY SOUTH.
HE LEADETH ME IN THE PATH OF
RIGHTEOUSNESS FOR HIS NAMESAKE.
YE THOUGH I WALK-THROUGH THE
VALLEY OF THE SHADOW OF DEATH, I
WILL FEAR NO EVIL, FOR THOUGH
ART WITH ME BY ROD AND BY STAFF
THEY COMFORT ME.
THOU PREPARE US THE TABLE BEFORE
ME IN THE PRESENCE OF MY
ENEMIES, THOU ANOINT MY HEAD
WITH OIL, MY CUP RUNNETH OVER.
SURELY, GOODNESS AND MERCY THAT
FOLLOW ME ALL THE DAYS OF MY
LIFE, AND I WILL DWELL IN THE
HOUSE OF THE LORD FOREVER.
>> LET US PRAY.
GOD IN HEAVEN, WE THANK YOU FOR
YOUR PRESENCE WITH US HERE ON
EARTH.
WE KNOW THAT THE CHILDREN WHO
WERE LOST IN THIS TRAGEDY FIRST
BELONGED TO YOU BEFORE THEY
BELONGED TO US.
AND WE COMMIT THEIR SOULS TO
YOU, TO YOUR LOVING, ETERNAL
CARE.
WE THANK YOU, LORD, THAT THEY
ARE NOW IN A PLACE OF NO MORE
SICKNESS, NO MORE SADNESS, NO
MORE SUFFERING, AND NO MORE
SORROW, AS THERE IS FINALLY NO
MORE SIN IN THE PRESENCE OF YOU,
THEIR SAVIOR AND OURS.
DEAR LORD, AS WE LEAVE THE
CHILDREN THAT WE HAVE LOST IN
YOUR HANDS, WE ASK THAT BY YOUR
GRACE, YOU WOULD EMPOWER US TO
BLESS AND COMFORT THE CHILDREN
WHO ARE STILL HERE IN OUR HANDS.
PLEASE BE WITH THEM IN A SPECIAL
WAY AS THEY GRIEVE THE LOSS OF
SIBLINGS AND FRIENDS.
LIFE WILL NEVER BE THE SAME FOR
THEM.
WE ASK THAT YOU WOULD HELP THESE
PRECIOUS LITTLE ONES TO CARRY
THE SPIRITS OF THEIR LOST LOVED
ONES IN THEIR HEARTS AS THEY GO
ALONG LIVING THEIR LIVES TO ITS
FULLEST, ACCORDING TO YOUR WILL
FOR EACH OF THESE GIRLS AND
BOYS.
AND LORD, WE ASK MOST OF ALL
THAT YOU WOULD USE US TO BE A
SOURCE OF YOUR HEALING IN THE
MIDST OF THEIR WOUNDS.
THAT YOU WOULD USE THOSE OF US
WHOSE CHILDREN ARE CRYING FOR
HOPE AS A SOURCE OF YOUR HOPE IN
THE MIDST OF ANY HOPELESSNESS,
AS YOU ARE THE GOD OF HOPE.
USE US TO REPLACE THEIR ANXIETY
WITH YOUR PEACE, AS YOU ARE THE
GOD OF PEACE.
AND PLEASE, FILL THEIR HEARTS
WITH THE SENSE OF YOUR LOVE,
YOUR PRESENCE, YOUR POWER, AND
MOST OF ALL, A SENSE OF YOUR
CARE.
NOT KNOWING WHAT THE FUTURE
HOLDS, BUT KNOWING THAT YOU HOLD
IT, AS YOU HOLD THESE PRECIOUS
LITTLE ONES WHO ARE STILL WITH
US TODAY IN YOUR HANDS THROUGH
OUR HANDS.
AND LORD, WE ASK THIS ALL IN THE
NAME OF THE ONE WHO SAID, UNLESS
WE BECOME LIKE LITTLE CHILDREN,
WE CANNOT ENTER THE KINGDOM OF
GOD.
MAKE US ALL CHILDLIKE AND NOT
CHILDISH.
IN OUR THOUGHTS, IN OUR WORDS,
IN OUR ATTITUDES, ACTIONS AND
BEHAVIORS, NOT ONLY BEFORE
OTHERS, BUT BEFORE YOU, THAT WE
MAY LOOK TO YOU FOR BETTER DAYS
AHEAD.
AND THAT WE MAY FULFILL YOUR
PURPOSE FOR US ON THIS EARTH.
FOR WE PRAY ALL OF THIS IN THE
NAME OF OUR PRECIOUS LORD AND
SAVIOR, JESUS.
AMEN.
♪
>> IN THE NAME OF GOD, THE
COMPASSIONATE AND THE MERCIFUL,
THE MUSLIM COMMUNITY AT THE AL
HEDAYA MUSLIM CENTER IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AND THROUGHOUT THE
NATION, JOINS WITH OUR FELLOW
AMERICANS GRIEVING FOR THOSE WHO
DIED IN THIS SENSELESS TRAGEDY.
AND PRAYING FOR THEM AND THEIR
FAMILIES.
WE ASK GOD TO ASK THOSE LOST A
SPECIAL PLACE IN PARADISE, AND
WE ASK THEIR FAMILIES TO BE
GRANTED THE STRENGTH TO ENDURE
THE UNENDURABLE.
IT IS IN SUCH TIMES OF ALMOST
UNBEARABLE LOSS THAT WE SEEK THE
COMFORT WITH OUR CREATOR AND
THAT ARTIFICIAL DIVISIONS OF
FAITH FALL AWAY TO REVEAL A
NATION OF MOTHERS AND FATHERS,
BROTHERS AND SISTERS, SONS AND
DAUGHTERS ALL UNITED IN A DESIRE
TO BRING HEALING AND RENEWED
HOPE.
THE KORAN, ISLAM'S REVEALED
TEXT, TELLS US THAT GOD'S MERCY
AND COMPASSION ARE WITHOUT LIMIT
AND ALWAYS AVAILABLE FOR THOSE
WHO ASK.
GOD SAYS, WHEN MY SERVANTS
QUESTION YOU ABOUT ME, TELL THEM
THAT I AM NEAR.
I ANSWER THE PRAYER OF EVERY
PERSON WHO CALLS ON ME.
CHAPTER 2 VERSE 186, THE
KORAN -- IN THE KORAN, GOD ALSO
SAYS, GIVE GLAD TIDINGS TO THOSE
WHO ENDURE WITH PATIENCE, WHO
WHEN AFFLICTED WITH CALAMITY
SAY, WE BELONG TO GOD AND TO HIM
WE SHALL RETURN.
SUCH ARE THE PEOPLE ON WHOM
THERE ARE BLESSINGS AND MERCY
FROM GOD.
CHAPTER 2, VERSE 155 TO 157.
SO LET US ALL, OF EVERY FAITH,
OF EVERY BACKGROUND, PRAY FOR
GOD'S COMFORT AT THIS TIME OF
HEARTBREAKING TRAGEDY.
BARELY, WITH EVERY DIFFICULT,
THERE IS EASE.
BARELY, WITH EVERY DIFFICULTY,
THERE IS EASE, CHAPTER 94, VERSE
5 THROUGH 6.
AMEN.
>> A PRAYER FOR THE FIRST
RESPONDERS.
LET US PRAY.
HOLY GOD, MANY OF THESE MEN AND
WOMEN YOU CALLED INTO SERVICE
WHEN THEY WERE JUST CHILDREN.
THEY WANTED TO BE POLICE
OFFICERS AND FIREFIGHTERS AND
CARE FOR THOSE THAT WERE IN
NEED, LORD.
YOU GAVE THEM GIFTS FOR THEIR
LIFE TO SERVE.
YOU ASKED THEM TO PAY A HIGH
PRICE FOR ALL THE SKILLS THAT
THEY HAVE BEEN GIVEN, FOR THE
STRENGTH THAT THEY HAVE.
YOU EQUIPPED THEM.
YOU GAVE THEM A WILLINGNESS TO
LEARN, TO TRAIN, TO STUDY.
SERVE IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT
WHEN A CALL WOULD COME IN.
AND YOU GAVE THEM THE
WILLINGNESS TO RESPOND WHEN THIS
TOWN NEEDED THEM THE MOST.
LORD, WE THANK YOU FOR THOSE IN
THIS TOWN THAT RESPONDED, BUT WE
THANK YOU ALSO FOR THOSE
THROUGHOUT THE STATE THAT CAME
WHEN THE NEED WAS GIVEN.
WE THANK YOU, LORD, FOR THEIR
GIFTS AND THEIR STRENGTH AND
THEIR COURAGE.
SO WE ASK YOU, LORD, TO WALK
WITH THEM IN THE DAYS AHEAD, TO
SURROUND THEM WITH YOUR ANGELS,
TO GIVE THEM PEOPLE WHO WILL
LISTEN TO THEIR STORY, TO LISTEN
TO WHAT THEY SAW THAT WAS NOT
FOR ANYONE TO EVER SEE.
LORD, WE PLACE EACH AND EVERY
ONE OF THESE MEN AND WOMEN IN
YOUR CARE, BUT WE WILL BE
FAITHFUL TO THEM.
WE WILL CARE FOR THEM.
WE WILL CONTINUE TO EQUIP THEM,
AND WE WILL KEEP THEM EVER IN
OUR PRAYERS.
AMEN.
>> FOR THE MOTHERS AND THE
FATHERS AND THE BROTHERS AND
SISTERS, THE GRANDPARENTS.
FOR ALL OF YOU TODAY.
THIS IS A SACRED TEXT FROM THE
BAHA'I FAITH.
IT WAS WRITTEN AS A LETTER TO A
MOTHER WHO WAS MOURNING THE LOSS
OF HER CHILD.
I'VE ADAPTED IT FOR THIS
EVENING.
ALTHOUGH THE LOSS OF A CHILD IS
INDEED HEARTBREAKING AND BEYOND
THE LIMITS OF HUMAN ENDURANCE,
YET ONE WHO KNOWETH AND
UNDERSTANDETH IS ASSURED THAT
THE CHILD HAD NOT BEEN LOST, BUT
RATHER HAVE STEPPED FROM THIS
WORLD INTO ANOTHER, AND YOU WILL
FIND THEM IN THE DEVINE REALM.
THAT REUNION SHALL BE FOR
ETERNITY, WHILE IN THIS WORLD,
SEPARATION IS INEVITABLE AND
BRINGETH WITH IT A BURNING
GRIEF.
PRAISE BE UNTO GOD THAT THOU HAS
FAITH.
TURNING THY FAITH TO THE
EVERLASTING KINGDOM AND BELIEVE
IN THE EXISTENCE OF A HEAVENLY
WORLD.
THEREFORE, BE THOUGH NOT
DISCONSULATE.
DO NOT LANGUISH.
DO NOT SIGH.
NEITHER WAIL, NOR WEEP, FOR
AGITATION AND MOURNING DEEPLY
EFFECT THE SOUL, THEIR SOUL, IN
THE DEVINE REALM.
>> THAT BELOVED CHILD ADDRESS
FROM THE HIDDEN WORLD.
OH, THOU KIND MOTHER AND FATHER,
THANK DEVINE PROVIDENCE THAT I
HAVE BEEN FREED FROM A SMALL AND
GLOOMY CAGE, AND LIKE THE BIRDS
OF THE MEADOWS, HAVE SOARED TO
THE DEVINE WORLD, A WORLD WHICH
IS SPACIOUS, ILLUMINED AND EVER
JOYOUS AND JUBILANT.
THEREFORE, LAMENT NOT, OH,
MOTHER AND FATHER, AND BE NOT
GRIEVED.
I AM NOT OF THE LOST, NOR HAVE I
BEEN OBLITERATED AND DESTROYED.
I HAVE SHAKEN OFF THE MORTAL
FORM AND HAVE RAISED MY BANNER
IN THIS SPIRITUAL WORLD.
FOLLOWING THIS SEPARATION IS
EVERLASTING COMPANIONSHIP.
THOU SHALT FIND ME IN THE HEAVEN
OF THE LORD, IMMERSED IN AN
OCEAN OF LIGHT.
>> GOD, WE CALL YOU BY MANY
NAMES.
MODERN EYE, GREAT SPIRIT, HIGHER
POWER, DEVINE ONE, BUT HOWEVER
WE ADDRESS YOU, YOU ARE ALWAYS
FATHER AND MOTHER TO US ALL, AND
WE ARE YOUR CHILDREN.
WE ARE YOUR FAMILY.
WE ASK YOUR BLESSING, LORD, UPON
THE COUNSELORS AND THE CLERGY
AND ALL THE CAREGIVERS AMONG US.
THEY HAVE GREAT PASSION FOR WHAT
THEY DO AND WHEN EVERYONE DOES
THEIR PASSION, WE ARRIVE AT
COMPASSION, AND WE THANK YOU.
WE KNOW THAT YOU'RE MOST AWARE
OF THEIR NEEDS.
THEY, TOO, BECOME TIRED AND
SOMETIMES CLOSE TO BURNING OUT.
HOW MUCH WE NEED ONE ANOTHER.
WHEN YOU CALL JEREMIAH OR AMOS
OR BARUK AND ALL YOUR PRECIOUS
APOSTLES AND PROPHETS, THEY
HEDGED AT FIRST.
BUT EACH TIME, IN TURN, THEY
GAVE THEIR YES AND THEY FOLLOWED
YOU.
KNOWING THAT YOU WERE ALWAYS
AMONG THEM, ALWAYS SUPPORTING
THEM.
THEY WERE CONDUITS FOR YOUR EYES
AND YOUR EARS AND YOUR VOICE AND
YOUR HANDS.
THEY WERE THE CLAY KNOWING THAT
YOU ALWAYS WERE THE POTTER, AND
THEY WERE RESILIENT IN YOUR
HANDS.
WHEN JESUS FELT THE NEED TO GET
AWAY FOR SOME RESPITE HIMSELF,
HE WENT TO THE MOUNTAINS OR INTO
THE WILDERNESS OR OUT TO THE
SEASHORE, AND THE GREAT NUMBERS
OF PEOPLE IN NEED ALWAYS
FOLLOWED.
TIRED AND DRAINED AS HE WAS, HE
LOOKED ON THEM WITH COMPASSION.
ANOINT ALL YOUR PEOPLE, LORD,
ALL THOSE WHO MINISTER TO YOU AS
THEY MINISTER TO ONE ANOTHER AND
ESPECIALLY THIS WEEK AS THEY
MINISTER TO THE BODY, MIND, AND
SPIRIT, TO THE WHOLE COMMUNITY
OF SANDY HOOK AND NEWTOWN.
A MODEL FOR THE NATION, A MODEL
FOR THE WORLD, AND WE THANK YOU
FOR THE WORLD'S SUPPORT,
CALLING, E-MAILING, TEXTING
THEIR LOVE AND THEIR COMMITMENT
TO BE ONE WITH US.
USE THEM, LORD.
TAKE THE PASSION THAT EACH ONE
HAS AND TRANSFORM IT TOTALLY,
COMPLETELY INTO YOUR SPIRIT OF
COMPASSION.
AND WE ASK THIS ALL, AMEN.
AMEN.
>> NEWTOWN IS A PLACE THAT LOVES
CHILDREN ABOVE ALL.
FAMILIES MOVE TO NEWTOWN BECAUSE
WE ARE A CARING AND LOVING
COMMUNITY.
WE ARE ALSO A PLACE THAT HAS
GREAT PRIDE IN OUR SCHOOLS,
PRIDE THAT PROPELS THE STUDENTS
IN THOSE SCHOOLS WITH THEIR
OUTSTANDING TEACHERS AND
ADMINISTRATORS TO HIGH
ACHIEVEMENT AND GREAT PERSONAL
WORTH.
THE HORROR THAT WAS VISITED UPON
OUR SANDY HOOK SCHOOL WAS NOT
DESERVED.
IT IS THE ANGRY AND DESPERATE
ACT OF A CONFUSED YOUNG MAN.
THERE IS NO BLAME TO BE LAID ON
US, BUT THERE IS A GREAT BURDEN
AND A GREAT CHALLENGE THAT WE
EMERGE WHOLE, THAT THESE
FAMILIES DEVASTATED BY
UNSPEAKABLE HARM KNOW AND TRUST
THAT WE LOVE THEM AND WILL DO
EVERYTHING WE CAN TO HELP THEM
HEAL.
I KNOW THAT NEWTOWN WILL
PREVAIL, THAT WE WILL NOT FALL
TO ACTS OF VIOLENCE.
IT IS A DEFINING MOMENT FOR OUR
TOWN, BUT IT DOES NOT DEFINE US.
WE ARE NEWTOWN, A SPECIAL AND
CARING PLACE.
WE ARE DEFINED BY ACTS OF
COURAGE, BY ACTS OF LOVE, AND BY
OUR CONTINUING COMMITMENT AND
LOVE FOR OUR CHILDREN AND
FAMILIES.
IT IS MY PLEASURE, LADIES AND
GENTLEMEN, TO PRESENT TO YOU
GOVERNOR DAN MALLOY.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> PAT, THANK YOU FOR ALL OF THE
GREAT WORK THAT YOU HAVE DONE
FOR THIS COMMUNITY IN THE LAST
THREE DAYS, TO THE POLICE CHIEF,
AND TO THE SUPERINTENDENT OF
SCHOOLS, THANK YOU FOR YOUR
GREAT SERVICE, AS WELL AS TO ALL
OF THE FIRST RESPONDERS.
THANK YOU.
WHEN I CAME IN TO THE HALL, ONE
OF THE FIRST SONGS TO BE PLAYED
ON THE PIANO WAS "AMAZING
GRACE," WHICH IS FITTING FOR ANY
NUMBER OF REASONS.
IT'S BECOME AN ANTHEM FOR FIRST
RESPONDERS, IT HAS GREAT WORDS,
IT ALSO SPEAKS OF THE POWER OF
FAITH.
"AMAZING GRACE" WAS WRITTEN BY A
FORMER SEA CAPTAIN ENGAGED IN
THE SLAVE TRADE.
AND THOSE PROFOUND WORDS THAT "I
ONCE WAS LOST BUT NOW AM FOUND"
SPEAK TO US ON A DAY LIKE TODAY.
WHEN WE ARE CALLED UPON, DARE I
SAY REQUIRED TO BE INVESTED IN
OUR FAITH, A FAITH SO EVIDENT IN
THIS ROOM AND IN THIS COMMUNITY
AT THIS TIME.
A FAITH THAT IS, AFTER ALL, AT
ITS VERY CORE, A GIFT FROM GOD.
A FAITH IN WHICH WE FIND COMFORT
AND HOPE AND COMPASSION.
A FAITH IN WHICH WE ARE GIVEN
THE POWER TO GO ON.
TO SURVIVE THAT WHICH HAS
BEFALLEN THIS COMMUNITY, THESE
FAMILIES, THESE SPOUSES, THAT
WHICH HAS HAPPENED AND IS
UNIMAGINABLE AND UNTHINKABLE AND
WAS NEVER, WE THOUGHT, INTENDED
TO BE VISITED UPON US HERE IN
CONNECTICUT OR IN NEWTOWN OR IN
SANDY HOOK.
I CHOOSE TO THINK ABOUT THE FACT
THAT IN THE COMING DAYS WE WILL
OFFICIALLY ENTER WINTER.
AND THAT IS ALWAYS TO BE
FOLLOWED BY THE SPRING.
LET ME ASSURE YOU THAT IN
WINTER, EACH TIME I SEE THE
BEGINNING OF A SNOWFALL, I WILL
BE THINKING OF THOSE 27 SOULS
LOST JUST A FEW DAYS AGO.
EACH TIME THE DAY GETS A LITTLE
LONGER, I WILL THINK AND DREAM
OF THE LIVES THAT MIGHT HAVE
BEEN AND THE LIVES THAT WERE SO
FULL OF GRACE.
AND WHEN THE FLOWERS START TO
COME OUT OF THE GROUND, AND WHEN
THEY RISE UP, I WILL KNOW THAT
WE ARE IN TOUCH WITH THOSE THAT
WE HAVE LOST IN THE LAST FEW
DAYS.
WE WILL GO ON.
WE WILL FIND STRENGTH.
FAITH IS A GIFT, AS IS OUR
ABILITY TO SUPPORT ONE ANOTHER
IN OUR GREATER COMMUNITY.
TO ALL OF YOU, I EXTEND MY MOST
PROFOUND CONDOLENCES ON BEHALF
OF ALL OF YOUR FELLOW CITIZENS
FOR WHAT YOU HAVE SEEN, WHAT YOU
HAVE WITNESSED, AND WHAT YOU
HAVE PERSONALLY EXPERIENCED.
WE WILL MOVE ON, WE WILL NEVER
FORGET, WE WILL IN MANY WAYS BE
MADE STRONGER FOR WHAT HAS
TRANSPIRED, AND WE WILL GET
BETTER.
WE ARE BLESSED TODAY TO HAVE
WITH US THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES, WHO UPON MEETING
WITH PAT AND I JUST A LITTLE
WHILE AGO, SAID THAT THE MOST
DIFFICULT DAY OF HIS PRESIDENCY
WAS FRIDAY WHEN HE HEARD THE
NEWS OF THAT WHICH HAD BEFALLEN
THIS COMMUNITY.
I ASSURED HIM THAT CONNECTICUT,
NEWTOWN, AND SANDY HOOK ARE
STRONG, AND I WELCOMED HIM ON
YOUR BEHALF TO OUR COMMUNITY.
I NOW INTRODUCE THE PRESIDENT OF
THE UNITED STATES.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU, GOVERNOR.
TO ALL THE FAMILIES, FIRST
RESPONDERS, TO THE COMMUNITY OF
NEWTOWN, CLERGY, GUESTS,
SCRIPTURE TELLS US DO NOT LOSE
HEART.
THOUGH OUTWARDLY WE ARE WASTING
AWAY, INWARDLY, WE ARE BEING
RENEWED DAY BY DAY.
FOR LIGHT AND MOMENTARY TROUBLES
ARE ACHIEVING FOR US AN ETERNAL
GLORY THAT FAR OUTWEIGHS THEM
ALL, SO WE FIX OUR EYES NOT ON
WHAT IS SEEN, BUT ON WHAT IS
UNSEEN.
SINCE WHAT IS SEEN IS TEMPORARY,
BUT WHAT IS UNSEEN IS ETERNAL.
FOR WE KNOW THAT IF THE EARTHLY
TENT WE LIVE IN IS DESTROYED, WE
HAVE A BUILDING FROM GOD, AN
ETERNAL HOUSE IN HEAVEN NOT
BUILT BY HUMAN HANDS.
WE GATHER HERE IN MEMORY OF 20
BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN AND SIX
REMARKABLE ADULTS.
THEY LOST THEIR LIVES IN A
SCHOOL THAT COULD HAVE BEEN ANY
SCHOOL IN A QUIET TOWN FULL OF
GOOD AND DECENT PEOPLE THAT
COULD BE ANY TOWN IN AMERICA.
HERE IN NEWTOWN, I COME TO OFFER
THE LOVE AND PRAYERS OF A
NATION.
I AM VERY MINDFUL THAT MERE
WORDS CANNOT MATCH THE DEPTHS OF
YOUR SORROW, NOR CAN THEY HEAL
YOUR WOUNDED HEARTS.
I CAN ONLY HOPE IT HELPS FOR YOU
TO KNOW THAT YOU'RE NOT ALONE IN
YOUR GRIEF.
THAT OUR WORLD, TOO, HAS BEEN
TORN APART.
THAT ALL ACROSS THIS LAND OF
OURS, WE HAVE WEPT WITH YOU.
WE'VE PULLED OUR CHILDREN TIGHT,
AND YOU MUST KNOW THAT WHATEVER
MEASURE OF COMFORT WE CAN
PROVIDE, WE WILL PROVIDE.
WHATEVER PORTION OF SADNESS THAT
WE CAN SHARE WITH YOU TO EASE
THIS HEAVY LOAD, WE WILL GLADLY
BEAR IT.
NEWTOWN, YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
AS THESE DIFFICULT DAYS HAVE
UNFOLDED, YOU'VE ALSO INSPIRED
US.
WITH STORIES OF STRENGTH AND
RESOLVE AND SACRIFICE.
WE KNOW THAT WHEN DANGER ARRIVED
IN THE HALLS OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY, THE SCHOOL'S STAFF
DID NOT FLINCH.
THEY DID NOT HESITATE.
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG AND MARY
SHERLACH, VICKI SOTO, LAUREN
RUSSEAU, RACHEL DAVINO AND
ANNE MARIE MURPHY, THEY ALL
RESPONDED IN HOW WE HOPE WE ALL
WOULD RESPOND IN SUCH TERRIFYING
CIRCUMSTANCES, WITH COURAGE AND
WITH LOVE, GIVING THEIR LIVES TO
PROTECT THE CHILDREN IN THEIR
CARE.
WE KNOW THAT THERE WERE OTHER
TEACHERS WHO BARRICADED
THEMSELVES INSIDE CLASSROOMS AND
KEPT STEADY THROUGH IT ALL AND
REASSURED THEIR STUDENTS BY
SAYING WAIT FOR THE GOOD GUYS,
THEY ARE COMING.
SHOW ME YOUR SMILE.
AND WE KNOW THAT GOOD GUYS CAME,
THE FIRST RESPONDERS WHO RACED
TO THE SCENE HELPING TO GUIDE
THOSE IN HARM'S WAY TO SAFETY
AND COMFORT THOSE IN NEED,
HOLDING AT BAY THEIR OWN SHOCK
AND THEIR OWN TRAUMA, BECAUSE
THEY HAD A JOB TO DO AND OTHERS
NEEDED THEM MORE.
AND THEN THERE WERE THE SCENES
OF THE SCHOOL CHILDREN HELPING
ONE ANOTHER, HOLDING EACH OTHER,
DUTIFULLY FOLLOWING INSTRUCTIONS
IN THE WAY THAT YOUNG CHILDREN
SOMETIMES DO.
ONE CHILD EVEN TRYING TO
ENCOURAGE A GROWNUP BY SAYING,
"I KNOW KARATE, SO IT'S OKAY,
I'LL LEAD THE WAY OUT."
AS A COMMUNITY, YOU'VE INSPIRED
US, NEWTOWN.
IN THE FACE OF INDESCRIBABLE
VIOLENCE, IN THE FACE OF
UNCONSCIONABLE EVIL, YOU'VE
LOOKED OUT FOR EACH OTHER.
YOU'VE CARED FOR ONE ANOTHER.
AND YOU'VE LOVED ONE ANOTHER.
THIS IS HOW NEWTOWN WILL BE
REMEMBERED, AND WITH TIME AND
GOD'S GRACE, THAT LOVE WILL SEE
YOU THROUGH.
BUT WE AS A NATION, WE ARE LEFT
WITH SOME HARD QUESTIONS.
SOMEONE ONCE DESCRIBED THE JOY
AND ANXIETY OF PARENTHOOD AS THE
EQUIVALENT OF HAVING YOUR HEART
OUTSIDE OF YOUR BODY ALL THE
TIME, WALKING AROUND.
WITH THEIR VERY FIRST CRY, THIS
MOST PRECIOUS, VITAL PART OF
OURSELVES, OUR CHILD.
SUDDENLY EXPOSED TO THE WORLD
THE POSSIBLE MISHAP OR MALICE,
AND EVERY PARENT KNOWS THERE'S
NOTHING WE WILL NOT DO TO SHIELD
OUR CHILDREN FROM HARM, AND YET
WE ALSO KNOW THAT WITH THAT
CHILD'S VERY FIRST STEP AND EACH
STEP AFTER THAT, THEY ARE
SEPARATING FROM US.
THAT WE WON'T -- THAT WE CAN'T
ALWAYS BE THERE FOR THEM.
THEY WILL SUFFER SICKNESS AND
SETBACKS AND BROKEN HEARTS AND
DISAPPOINTMENTS, AND WE LEARN
THAT OUR MOST IMPORTANT JOB IS
TO GIVE THEM WHAT THEY NEED TO
BECOME SELF RELIANT AND CAPABLE
AND RESILIENT, READY TO FACE THE
WORLD WITHOUT FEAR.
AND WE KNOW WE CAN'T DO THIS BY
OURSELVES.
IT COMES AS A SHOCK AT A CERTAIN
POINT WHERE YOU REALIZE NO
MATTER HOW MUCH YOU LOVE THESE
KIDS, YOU CAN'T DO IT BY
YOURSELF.
THAT THIS JOB OF KEEPING OUR
CHILDREN SAFE AND TEACHING THEM
WELL IS SOMETHING WE CAN ONLY DO
TOGETHER.
WITH THE HELP OF FRIENDS AND
NEIGHBORS, THE HELP OF A
COMMUNITY AND THE HELP OF A
NATION.
AND IN THAT WAY WE COME TO
REALIZE THAT WE BEAR
RESPONSIBILITY FOR EVERY CHILD,
BECAUSE WE'RE COUNTING ON
EVERYBODY ELSE TO HELP LOOK
AFTER OURS.
THAT WE'RE ALL PARENTS, THAT
THEY ARE ALL OUR CHILDREN.
THIS IS OUR FIRST TASK, CARING
FOR OUR CHILDREN.
OUR FIRST JOB.
IF WE DON'T GET THAT RIGHT, WE
DON'T GET ANYTHING RIGHT.
THAT'S HOW, AS A SOCIETY, WE
WILL BE JUDGED.
AND BY THAT MEASURE, CAN WE
TRULY SAY, AS A NATION, THAT
WE'RE MEETING OUR OBLIGATIONS?
CAN WE HONESTLY SAY THAT WE'RE
DOING ENOUGH TO KEEP OUR
CHILDREN, ALL OF THEM, SAFE FROM
HARM?
CAN WE CLAIM, AS A NATION, THAT
WE'RE ALL TOGETHER THERE,
LETTING THEM KNOW THEY ARE LOVED
AND TEACHING THEM TO LOVE IN
RETURN?
CAN WE SAY THAT WE'RE TRULY
DOING ENOUGH TO GIVE ALL THE
CHILDREN OF THIS COUNTRY THE
CHANCE THEY DESERVE TO LIVE OUR
THEIR LIVES IN HAPPINESS AND
WITH PURPOSE?
I'VE BEEN REFLECTING ON THIS THE
LAST FEW DAYS, AND IF WE'RE
HONEST WITH OURSELVES, THE
ANSWER'S NO.
WE'RE NOT DOING ENOUGH.
AND WE WILL HAVE TO CHANGE.
SINCE I'VE BEEN PRESIDENT, THIS
IS THE FOURTH TIME WE HAVE COME
TOGETHER TO COMFORT A GRIEVING
COMMUNITY TORN APART BY MASS
SHOOTINGS.
FOURTH TIME WE'VE HUGGED
SURVIVORS, THE FOURTH TIME WE'VE
CONSOLED THE FAMILIES OF
VICTIMS, AND IN BETWEEN, THERE
HAVE BEEN AN ENDLESS SERIES OF
DEADLY SHOOTINGS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY, DAILY REPORTS OF
VICTIMS, MANY OF THEM CHILDREN,
IN SMALL TOWNS AND CITIES ALL
ACROSS AMERICA.
VICTIMS WHO MUCH OF THE TIME
THEIR ONLY FAULT WAS BEING AT
THE WRONG PLACE AT THE WRONG
TIME.
WE CAN'T TOLERATE THIS ANYMORE.
THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
AND TO END THEM, WE MUST CHANGE.
WE WILL BE TOLD THAT THE CAUSES
OF SUCH VIOLENCE ARE COMPLEXED,
AND THAT IS TRUE.
NO SINGLE LAW, NO SET OF LAWS
CAN ELIMINATE EVIL FROM THE
WORLD OR PREVENT EVERY SENSELESS
ACT OF VIOLENCE IN OUR SOCIETY,
BUT THAT CAN'T BE AN EXCUSE FOR
AN ACTION.
SURELY WE CAN DO BETTER THAN
THIS.
IF THERE'S EVEN ONE STEP WE CAN