>>> ANA, DYLAN, MADELEINE,
CATHERINE, CHASE, JESSE, JAMES,
GRACE, EMILIE, JACK, NOAH,
CAROLINE, JESSICA, BENJAMIN,
AVIELLE, ALLISON -- GOD HAS
CALLED THEM ALL HOME.
FOR THOSE OF US WHO REMAIN, LET
US FIND THE STRENGTH TO CARRY ON
AND MAKE OUR COUNTRY WORTHY OF
THEIR MEMORY.
>> A TOUGH THING THIS MORNING.
>>> HAPPENING NOW IN THE NEWS
ROOM, AMID ONE MAN'S UNSPEAKABLE
CRUELTY, TALES OF COURAGE ARE
EMERGING FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
AS SHOTS DREW NEARER, TEACHER
VICTORIA SOTO THREW HERSELF
BETWEEN THE GUNMAN AND HER
STUDENTS.
HER FAMILY TELLS US HOW SHE
SHOULD BE REMEMBERED.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA COMFORTING
THE FAMILIES OF THOSE KILLED AND
HOW HE REMEMBERS THE LOVE AND
PRAYERS OF A NATION.
WE'LL SHARE HIS SPEECH FROM LAST
NIGHT'S VIGIL.
PART OF THE SPEECH, A CALL TO
ACTION.
PRESIDENT OBAMA VOWING TO
PREVENT ANOTHER MASSACRE.
TODAY GUN CONTROL SEEMS TO HAVE
A TONE OF DETERMINATION.
A SPECIAL EDITION OF "NEWSROOM"
BEGINS RIGHT NOW.
>>> GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
I'M CAROL COSTELLO HERE IN
ATLANTA.
JOINING ME SHORTLY, DON LEMON.
HEES IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
LET'S BEGIN HERE, SHALL WE?
WE'LL BEGIN WITH THE LATEST AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
TODAY THE FIRST OF THE FUNERALS
GET UNDER WAY.
6-YEAR-OLD JACK PINTO AND NOAH
POZNER WILL BE THE FIRST OF THE
26 VICTIMS LAID TO REST.
WE'LL ALSO LEARNING MORE ABOUT
THE REMARKABLE ACTS OF HEROISM.
ONE TEACHER, ANN MARIE MURPHY,
DIED WHILE SHIELDING STUDENTS
WITH HER BODY.
ANOTHER READ TO KIDS TO DISTRACT
THEM FROM THE GUNSHOTS THAT
EXPLODED OUTSIDE THEIR ROOM.
LAST NIGHT IN NEWTOWN, PRESIDENT
OBAMA MET WITH SURVIVORS AND THE
FAMILIES OF THOSE KILLED.
HE VOWED TO PREVENT ANOTHER
MASSACRE AND CALLED FOR A
NATIONAL DISCUSSION ON GUN
VIOLENCE.
MORE ON THE GUN CONTROL DEBATE
IN JUST A MOMENT.
BUT FIRST THE PRESIDENT'S
MESSAGE TO A COMMUNITY IN
ANGUISH.
HERE ARE SOME OF THE PRESIDENT'S
COMMENTS FROM LAST NIGHT'S
VIGIL.
>> I AM VERY MINDFUL THAT MER
WORDS CANNOT MATCH THE DEPTHS OF
YOUR SORROW, NOR CAN THEY HEAL
YOUR WOUNDED HEARTS.
I CAN ONLY HOPE IT HELPS FOR YOU
TO KNOW THAT YOU'RE NOT ALONE IN
YOUR GRIEF, THAT OUR WORLD TOO
HAS BEEN TORN APART.
THAT ALL ACROSS THIS LAND OF
OURS WE HAVE WEPT WITH YOU.
WE'VE PULLED OUR CHILDREN TIGHT.
AND YOU MUST KNOW THAT WHATEVER
MEASURE OF COMFORT WE CAN
PROVIDE, WE WILL PROVIDE.
WHATEVER PORTION OF SADNESS THAT
WE CAN SHARE WITH YOU TO EASE
THIS HEAVY LOAD, WE WILL GLADLY
BEAR.
NEWTOWN, YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
>> THE PRESIDENT'S WORDS ARE
PROVIDING A MEASURE OF COMFORT
FOR THE FAMILIES OF THOSE
KILLED.
AFTER LAST NIGHT'S VIGIL, WE
SPOKE WITH THE PARENTS AND
SIBLINGS OF VICKI SOTO.
SHE'S THE FIRST GRADE TEACHER
WHO WAS SHOOING HER STUDENTS
AWAY FROM THE DOOR WHEN THE
GUNMAN BURST IN AND SHOT HER.
>> I APPRECIATE ALL HIS KIND
WORDS THAT HE DID SAY ABOUT MY
SISTER.
SHE WAS A HERO, AND SHE STILL
IS.
>> I WOULD JUST LIKE EVERYONE TO
KNOW THAT SHE WAS JUST A
BEAUTIFUL, BEAUTIFUL YOUNG LADY.
SHE HAD SUCH PASSION FOR
TEACHING AND FOR LIFE, AND
ESPECIALLY FOR HER FAMILY.
SHE WAS EXTREMELY CLOSE TO HER
SIBLINGS THAT ARE SITTING WITH
ME AND HER COUSINS AND LOVED
THEM DEARLY AND WANTED TO BE A
TEACHER FROM THE TIME SHE WAS 3.
THAT'S ALL SHE EVER WANTED TO
DO, AND SHE JUST LOVED HER KIDS.
SHE JUST TALKED ABOUT THEM ALL
THE TIME WITH SUCH FONDNESS AND
CARING, AND SHE JUST ADORED
THEM.
I HAVE NO DOUBT IN MY MIND SHE
DID EVERYTHING SHE COULD TO
PROTECT EVERY SINGLE ONE OF
THEM.
>> INVESTIGATORS SAY VICKI SOTO
ALMOST CERTAINLY SAVED LIVES BY
ACTING SO QUICKLY.
THE NEWTOWN TRAGEDY IS THE
NATION'S FOURTH MASS SHOOTING IN
JUST THE PAST TWO YEARS, AND IN
THE AFTERMATH OF EACH,
CONVERSATION NATURALLY TURNS TO
THE ISSUE OF GUN CONTROL.
THIS TIME, HOWEVER, THE TONE
SEEMS DIFFERENT.
LISTEN TO THE PRESIDENT'S
RESOLVE IN HIS SPEECH LAST
NIGHT.
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS, I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT TO MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS TO PARENTS
AND EDUCATORS IN AN EFFORT AIMED
AT PREVENTING MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS.
>> CNN'S DAN LOTHIAN IS AT THE
WHITE HOUSE THIS MORNING.
DAN, THE PRESIDENT VOWED ACTION,
BUT HE OFFERED NO SPECIFICS.
WHAT KIND OF REFORMS COULD HE
PUSH FOR?
>> Reporter: WELL, I THINK, AS
SOME PEOPLE HAVE POINTED OUT,
MAYBE DURING THAT SERVICE WASN'T
THE TIME FOR THE PRESIDENT TO BE
LAYING OUT ANY SPECIFICS, BUT A
COUPLE OF THINGS WE COULD SEE
THE PRESIDENT DO, FIRST OF ALL,
THERE'S THE ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN
WHICH EXPIRED IN 2004.
THAT HAD BEEN IN PLACE FOR TEN
YEARS.
THE PRESIDENT DURING THE 2008
CAMPAIGN SAID HE SUPPORTED IT,
BUT THERE WAS NO REAL MOVEMENT
IN THAT AREA.
IN FACT, THE BRADY CENTER TO
PREVENT GUN VIOLENCE SAID AFTER
THE PRESIDENT'S FIRST YEAR IN
OFFICE WAS A, QUOTE, ABJECT
FAILURE WHEN IT COMES TO THIS
ISSUE.
WE COULD SEE THE PRESIDENT PUT
MORE PRESSURE ON LAWMAKERS TO
REINSTATE THAT ASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN.
PERHAPS THE PRESIDENT COULD ALSO
FOCUS ON STRENGTHENING MENTAL
HEALTH LAWS THAT WOULD PREVENT
THOSE WITH DIFFICULT MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES FROM GETTING THESE
DANGEROUS WEAPONS AND THEN
CARRYING OUT THESE MASS
SHOOTINGS.
THOSE ARE SOME OF THE AREAS
WHERE WE COULD SEE THE PRESIDENT
PUSH.
BUT, AGAIN, WE HAVEN'T HEARD THE
PRESIDENT LAY OUT ANY SPECIFICS,
AND IT REALLY HASN'T BEEN A BIG
PRIORITY FOR THE PRESIDENT
DURING HIS FIRST FOUR YEARS, AND
WHEN IT COMES TO CONGRESS, THERE
HAVE BEEN SOME BILLS, SOME GUN
RELATED BILLS THAT HAVE BEEN PUT
FORWARD BUT REALLY WENT NOWHERE.
THERE IS SOME INDICATION NOW
THIS IS SOMETHING LAWMAKERS
COULD START LOOKING AT, BUT
WE'LL HAVE TO WAIT AND SEE,
CAROL.
>> DAN, SADLY, WE HAVE BEEN DOWN
THIS ROAD SO MANY TIMES, TOO
MANY TIMES.
NOTHING REALLY CHANGES.
I MEAN THAT AS FAR AS GUN
CONTROL LAWS GO, HELP FOR PEOPLE
WITH MENTAL ILLNESS, MORE MONEY
BEING POURED INTO PSYCHIATRIC
CENTERS OR COUNSELING CENTERS
THAT MIGHT HELP PEOPLE.
NOTHING IS EVER ACCOMPLISHED.
IS THE TONE DIFFERENT THIS TIME?
>> Reporter: THE TONE IS ALWAYS
DIFFERENT AFTER A MASS SHOOTING.
WE HEARD THE SAME THING AFTER
AURORA.
THE PRESIDENT HAS BEEN INVOLVED
OR HAD TO DEAL WITH FOUR MASS
SHOOTINGS DURING HIS PRESIDENCY,
AND THERE'S ALWAYS A LOT OF
TOUGH TALK, AND THIS DEBATE
REALLY INTENSIFIES IN THE DAYS
FOLLOWING THESE MASS SHOOTINGS,
BUT THEN NOTHING REALLY HAPPENS.
WE DO SEE A SLIGHTLY DIFFERENT
TONE WHERE YOU HEAR LAWMAKERS
TALKING ABOUT GOING UP TO
CAPITOL HILL AND REALLY PUSHING
FORWARD ON SOMETHING, BUT WE
DON'T KNOW.
WE'LL HAVE TO WAIT AND SEE.
RIGHT NOW THERE ARE A LOT OF
OTHER PRESSING, BIG PRESSING
ISSUES THAT ARE ALSO CRITICAL
HERE IN WASHINGTON.
THERE'S THE FISCAL CLIFF
OBVIOUSLY THAT NEEDS TO BE
RESOLVED BEFORE THE END OF THE
YEAR.
SO WE'LL HAVE TO SEE ONCE THOSE
ISSUES ARE DEALT WITH, WHETHER
OR NOT THERE WILL BE THIS
SERIOUS EFFORT TO DEAL WITH
GUNS.
>> WE'LL SEE.
DAN LOTHIAN REPORTING LIVE FROM
THE WHITE HOUSE THIS MORNING.
LOOKING AT THAT PICTURE THERE
BESIDE DAN.
WE'RE ACTUALLY AWAITING A NEWS
CONFERENCE FROM NEWTOWN.
AUTHORITIES EXPECTED TO BRIEF
REPORTERS ANY MOMENT WHEN THAT
BEGINS.
WE'LL TAKE IT LIVE FOR YOU.
>>> LET'S HEAD TO NEWTOWN RIGHT
NOW TO CHECK IN WITH DON LEMON.
GOOD MORNING, DON.
>> CAROL, GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
WE ARE AWAITING A NEWS
CONFERENCE.
THEY HAVE BEEN GIVING THOSE NEWS
CONFERENCES JUST ABOUT EVERY
DAY, A COUPLE TIMES A DAY,
UPDATING THE PUBLIC ON EXACTLY
WHAT'S HAPPENING HERE IN
NEWTOWN, GIVING SPECIFICALLY AS
MANY DETAILS AS THEY CAN, NOT
RELEASING A TIMELINE, BUT
YESTERDAY RELEASING INFORMATION
ABOUT THE GUNS, ABOUT THE
VICTIM, AND ABOUT THE SUSPECT AS
WELL.
YOU KNOW, BY ALL ACCOUNTS SANDY
HOOK PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG,
SHE DID EVERYTHING, EVERYTHING
SHE COULD TO PREVENT FRIDAY'S
RAMPAGE.
SHE HAD A NEW SECURITY SYSTEM
INSTALLED IN THE SCHOOL.
AND WHEN THAT WASN'T ENOUGH, SHE
CONFRONTED THE GUNMAN HERSELF
WHILE YELLING TO TEACHERS TO
LOCK THEIR DOORS.
CNN'S GARY TUCHMAN TALKED
EXCLUSIVELY WITH HER HEARTBROKEN
FAMILY.
>> Reporter: PRINCIPAL DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG WAS QUITE A BIT
YOUNGER THAN HER HUSBAND GEORGE,
BUT WHEN THEY GOT MARRIED TEN
YEARS AGO, BOTH FOR THE SECOND
TIME, SHE WITH TWO DAUGHTERS AND
HE WITH THREE, GEORGE WAS
MARRYING HIS BOSS.
>> WHEN DAWN AND I MET, SHE WAS
THE ASSISTANT PRINCIPAL AT OUR
SCHOOL, AND I WAS A SEVENTH
GRADE MATH TEACHER AT THAT TIME.
I JUST FELL IN LOVE WITH HER.
>> Reporter: GEORGE MADE THE BIG
DECISION.
THE TIME HAD COME TO PROPOSE.
>> SHE TURNED ME DOWN FIVE
TIMES.
>> Reporter: YOU ASKED HER TO
MARRY YOU, BUT SHE TURNED YOU
DOWN?
>> FIVE TIMES.
>> Reporter: WHAT HAPPENED THE
SIXTH TIME?
>> THE SIXTH TIME, IWATE Y WAIT
UNTIL IT WASN'T SUCH ROUGH
SAILING.
>> Reporter: INDEED, GEORGE HAD
BEEN POPPING THE QUESTION ON A
SAILBOAT THEY OWNED TOGETHER.
>> I POPPED THE QUESTION ON A
SLOOP ON THE PACIFIC.
>> Reporter: BETH AND ANN ARE
GEORGE'S DAUGHTERS FROM HIS
FIRST MARRIAGE.
ERICA AND THE TEENAGER.
>> WE BUILT THIS BEAUTIFUL HOUSE
IN THE ADIRONDACKS, OUR DREAM.
OUR DREAM WAS A CHRONOLOGICAL
DREAM.
IT WAS GOING TO BE DAWN'S HOUSE
BECAUSE I WAS GOING TO DIE.
I'M MUCH OLDER THAN DAWN.
IT WAS GOING TO BE DAWN'S HOUSE
AND DAWN'S GRANDCHILDREN AND ALL
THESE CHILDREN COULD USE THE
HOUSE ON THE LAKE, AND IT WOULD
BE WONDERFUL.
WE BUILT ROOMS DOWNSTAIRS FOR
KIDS.
IT WAS GOING TO BE DAWN'S HOUSE
ULTIMATELY.
WITH ALL THE CHILDREN.
ALL THE CHILDREN.
AND NOW IT'S ME.
I CAN'T -- I DON'T THINK I CAN
DO THAT.
>> Reporter: I WANT TO REITERATE
TO YOU, GEORGE, YOU HAVE THESE
BEAUTIFUL DAUGHTERS AND
SON-IN-LAWS AND GRANDCHILDREN,
AND EVERYONE WILL BE HERE TO
TAKE CARE OF YOU.
IS THAT RIGHT, LADIES?
>> YES.
>> OF COURSE.
>> MY JOB HAS ALWAYS BEEN TO
TAKE CARE OF OTHER PEOPLE.
>> Reporter: IT'S ALL RIGHT IF
SOMEONE TAKES CARE OF YOU FOR A
WHILE.
>> NO ONE HAS EVER TAKEN CARE OF
ME.
>> STOP BEING SO STUBBORN.
>> Reporter: WHILE DAWN WAS AT
SANDY HOOK, GEORGE STILL TAUGHT
AT THE MIDDLE SCHOOL WHERE THEY
MET.
IN THE MIDDLE OF DAY, THIS IS
HOW GEORGE FOUND OUT WHAT
HAPPENED.
>> THE KIDS CAME UP WITH A
COMPUTER AND SAID SOMETHING HAS
HAPPENED AT ASANDY HOOK SCHOOL,
AND YOUR WIFE HAS BEEN KILLED.
>> Reporter: GEORGE RACED OUT OF
THE SCHOOL AND INTO A NIGHTMARE.
LIKE ALL THE FAMILIES OF
VICTIMS, THEY WANT TO KNOW MORE.
ON THIS DAY, THEY HAVE LEARNED
MORE.
TWO TEACHERS WHO SURVIVED TOLD
GEORGE THEY WERE HAVING A
MEETING WITH DAWN WHEN THE SHOTS
STARTED RINGING OUT.
>> DAWN PUT HERSELF IN JEOPARDY,
AND I HAVE BEEN ANGRY ABOUT
THAT.
ANGRY UNTIL JUST NOW, TODAY,
WHEN I MET THE TWO WOMEN THAT
SHE TOLD TO GO UNDER SHELTER
WHILE SHE ACTUALLY CONFRONTED
THE GUNMAN, AND SHE COULD NOT --
SHE COULD HAVE AVOIDED THAT, AND
SHE DIDN'T.
I KNEW SHE WOULDN'T.
SO I'M NOT ANGRY ANYMORE.
I'M NOT ANGRY.
I'M NOT ANGRY ANYMORE.
I'M JUST VERY SAD.
VERY SAD.
THEY SAID WE WERE AT THE
MEETING.
THERE WERE GUNSHOTS.
SOMEBODY SHOT THE WINDOW.
SOMEBODY CAME IN, INTO THE --
NOT INTO THE OFFICE, BUT INTO
THE BUILDING, THE FOYER OF THE
BUILDING, AND DAWN TOLD US TO GO
HIDE, AND SHE AND AT LEAST ONE
OTHER TEACHER RAN OUT AND
ACTUALLY TRIED TO SUBDUE THE
KILLER.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE THAT COMES
FROM.
DAWN WAS, WHAT, 5'2".
>> Reporter: EVERYONE HERE IS SO
PROUD, NO ONE MORE SO THAN
ERICA, WHO SAID HER MOM WAS
ALWAYS THERE FOR HER DAUGHTERS.
>> EVERY GAME SHE WAS THERE.
EVERY PRACTICE SHE WAS THERE.
ALL OF MY SISTER'S CHEERLEADING
STUFF, SHE WAS THERE.
EVERY DANCE COMPETITION.
SHE WAS DOING HOMEWORK ON THE
BLEACHERS, BUT SHE WAS THERE.
AND SHE WAS MY ROCK.
MY ROCK.
>> Reporter: AND NOW SHE IS A
HERO TOO.
FINAL THING I WANT TO ASK YOU IS
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY TO YOUR MOM
RIGHT NOW?
>> COME BACK.
JUST COME BACK.
>> CNN'S GARY TUCHMAN WITH DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG'S FAMILY.
CAROL, AS WE WAIT ON THIS PRESS
CONFERENCE, I HEARD YOU TALKING
TO OUR DAN LOTHIAN.
WOULDN'T IT BE GREAT IF THEY
WERE HOLDING A PRESS CONFERENCE
SO THAT PEOPLE DIDN'T HAVE TO
DEAL WITH THIS, ABOUT SOME
SENSIBLE GUN RULES IN THIS
COUNTRY AND WE WOULDN'T HAVE TO
DEAL WITH WHAT THE HOCHSPRUNG
FAMILY AND MANY OTHER FAMILIES
ARE DEALING WITH NOW, CAROL.
>> A LOT OF CONVERSATIONS HAVE
TO GO ON, DON, NOT JUST ABOUT
GUN L KRO, BUT ABOUT MENTAL
ILLNESS, AND SO MANY THINGS WE
JUST DON'T TALK ABOUT, AT LEAST
IN ANY IN DEPTH WAY.
DON LEMON, WE'LL STILL GET BACK
TO YOU.
WE'RE STILL WAITING FOR THAT
NEWS CONFERENCE FROM NEWTOWN,
LIEUTENANT VANCE OF THE STATE
POLICE AND THE MEDICAL
INSPECTOR.
>>> ONE OF THE UNANSWERED
QUESTIONS IN THIS TRAGIC
SHOOTING, WHO WERE NANCY AND
ADAM LANZA?
WHAT KIND OF LIFE DID THE MOTHER
AND SON LIVE BEFORE THE
SHOOTINGS IN CONNECTICUT?
WE'LL TAKE A CLOSER LOOK.
HAVE A GOOD NIGHT.
HERE YOU GO. YOU, TOO.
I'M GOING TO DREAM
ABOUT THAT STEAK.
ABOUT THAT TIRAMISU.
WHAT A NIGHT, HUH?
BUT, UM, CAN THE TEST DRIVE
BE OVER NOW?
HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A PASSAT.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN, $0 DUE AT SIGNING,
$0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAND.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
>>> 16 MINUTES PAST THE HOUR.
WE'RE STILL WAITING FOR THE NEWS
CONFERENCE TO BEGIN AT NEWTOWN.
EXPECTED TO BRIEF REPORTERS AT
ANY MOMENT NOW.
FIRST A CHECK OF SOME OF THE
OTHER STORIES WE'RE FOLLOWING
THIS MORNING.
>>> THREE MONTHS AFTER THE
DEADLY ATTACK AT THE U.S.
CONSULATE IN LIBYA, THE STATE
DEPARTMENT EXPECTED TO RECEIVE
AN INDEPENDENT REPORT ON THE
INCIDENT TODAY.
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON ORDERED THE REVIEW.
IT WILL BE PRESENTED TO CONGRESS
BEFORE A PRIVATE BRIEFING THIS
WEEK.
>>> THE U.S. AMBASSADOR TO LIBYA
CHRIS STEVENS AND THREE OTHERS
WERE KILLED IN THAT ATTACK ON
SEPTEMBER 11th.
>>> LOOKS LIKE HOUSE SPEAKER
JOHN BOEHNER IS PUTTING MORE ON
THE TABLE TO AVOID THAT FISCAL
CLIFF.
A SOURCE CLOSE TO THE TALKS
TELLS CNN BOEHNER IS OFFERING TO
RAISE THE DEBT CEILING.
SOMETHING REPUBLICANS OPPOSE.
HE'S ALSO PROPOSING HIGHER TAXES
FOR THOSE WHO MAKE $1 MILLION A
YEAR OR MORE.
PRESIDENT PUSHING FOR HIGHER
TAXES FOR THOSE MAKING $250,000
A YEAR.
>>> IN MONEY NEWS, SOME 6
MILLION CREDIT CARD HOLDERS WILL
GET A WELCOME GIFT, A REFUND.
DISCOVER AMERICAN EXPRESS AND
CAPITAL ONE GIVING BACK $435
MILLION AS ORDERED BY THE
GOVERNMENT AS PART OF A
CRACKDOWN ON DECEPTIVE
PRACTICES.
THE REFUND SHOULD BE OUT BY THE
END OF MARCH.
>>> IN THE WEATHER, PARTS OF THE
PACIFIC NORTHWEST ARE GETTING
HIT BY THE WORST STORM IN SIX
YEARS.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT MT. RAINIER.
A TOW TRUCK DRIVER WAS KILLED ON
SUNDAY WHEN HE WAS RUN OVER BY
ANOTHER CAR IN NEAR WHITEOUT
CONDITIONS.
THIS STORM COULD DROP THREE FEET
OF SNOW ON THE AREA.
>>> BACK TO NEWTOWN NOW.
THE BIG QUESTION, WHAT'S NEXT
FOR THE STUDENTS AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY?
WHEN WILL THEY BE RETURNING TOs
C
CLASSES?
CAN YOU IMAGINE SORTING THROUGH
ALL THAT?
CNN'S SANDRA ENDO HAS BEEN DOING
JUST THAT.
WHAT HAVE YOU FOUND OUT, SANDRA?
>> Reporter: WHEN A TRAGEDY LIKE
THIS HAPPENS, YOU HEAR EXPERTS
TALK ABOUT HOW IT'S SO IMPORTANT
FOR STUDENTS AND CHILDREN TO
RETAIN A SENSE OF ROUTINE AND A
TYPE OF NORMALCY, AND THAT'S
WHAT SCHOOL ADMINISTRATORS HERE
IN NEWTOWN ARE CERTAINLY HOPING
TO ACHIEVE FOR A LOT OF THE
STUDENTS AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
IT REMAINS A CRIME SCENE, SO
STUDENTS THERE CANNOT RETURN TO
CLASS.
WHAT ADMINISTRATORS ARE TRYING
TO DO, CAROL, THEY'RE TRYING TO
WORK OUT A PLAN WITH A
NEIGHBORING TOWN IN ORDER TO
ACCOMMODATE THE STUDENTS OF THAT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
SO SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
STUDENTS WILL LIKELY GO TO CHALK
HILL SCHOOL, WHICH IS IN MONROE,
ABOUT SEVEN MILES FROM HERE AS
EARLY AS THIS WEEK.
TODAY ALL NEWTOWN SCHOOLS ARE
CLOSED SO THAT STAFF CAN TALK TO
EXPERTS ON HOW TO TALK TO
STUDENTS AND HOW TO DEAL WITH
THIS TRAGEDY THAT HIT THIS TOWN.
TOMORROW ALL CLASSES ARE
EXPECTED TO RESUME FOR THOSE
SCHOOLS.
CAROL?
>> SANDRA ENDO, REPORTING LIVE
FOR US IT THIS MORNING.
>>> WE'RE ALSO LEARNING MORE
ABOUT THE MAN POLICE SAY WAS
RESPONSIBLE FOR THE SHOOTING AT
SANDY HOOK AND HIS MOTHER.
DON LEMON JOINS US ONCE AGAIN
FROM NEWTOWN WITH THAT PART OF
THE STORY.
>> THANK YOU, CAROL.
POLICE SAY ADAM LANZA'S FIRST
TARGET ON FRIDAY WAS HIS MOTHER.
SOME WHO KNEW NANCY LANZA CALL
HER A REASONABLE NEIGHBOR, A
FRIEND WHO -- A PERSONAL AND
REASONABLE NEIGHBOR.
A FRIEND WHO -- ONE OF HER SONS
CALL HER A SOCIAL BUTTERFLY.
IT'S A DIFFERENT STORY FOR HER
SON ADAM.
NANCY PULLED HER SON OUT OF THE
SCHOOL DISTRICT AND HOME
SCHOOLED HIM.
THOSE WHO KNEW ADAM REMEMBER HIM
FOR NOT STANDING OUT.
>> BASICALLY, HE WAS A QUIET,
SHY KID.
HE STOOD OUT TO ME BECAUSE OF
THE FACT HE DIDN'T INTERACT WITH
TOO MANY OTHER KIDS ON THE BUS.
HE WAS OLDER, I BELIEVE, WHEN I
HAD HIM.
THIS IS GOING BACK A FEW YEARS.
I DON'T RECALL EVERYTHING, BUT
THAT DID STAND OUT.
THE ONE THING ABOUT IT.
>> THE MORE WE LEARN ABOUT ADAM
LANZA, THE MORE CONFUSING IT
BECOMES.
CNN'S BRIAN TODD LOOKS DEEPER
INTO WHO HE WAS.
>> Reporter: HIS MOTIVE FOR THIS
UNSPEAKABLE ACT IS STILL NOT
CLEAR.
LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS SAY.
IN DIGGING FOR DETAILS ABOUT
SHOOTER ADAM LANZA AND HIS
FAMILY, ACCOUNTS EMERGE THAT ARE
STILL CONFUSING, SOMETIMES
CONFLICTING.
A NEIGHBOR WHO KNEW HIM IN
RECENT YEARS DESCRIBES LANZA AS
TROUBLED, BUT LISTEN TO THIS
ACCOUNT FROM A YOUNG MAN WHO
KNEW HIM.
>> HE WAS JUST A KID.
>> Reporter: JUST A KID?
>> JUST A KID.
>> Reporter: NEVER ANTISOCIAL?
>> NO.
ADAM'S GOT -- NO.
>> Reporter: TROUBLE MAKER?
>> NO, DEFINITELY NOT.
>> Reporter: NOTICEABLE?
DID HE JUST KIND OF BLEND INTO
THE BACKGROUND?
>> YEAH.
NOTHING THAT WOULD WARRANT ANY
OF THIS.
>> Reporter: RYAN KRAFT SAYS HE
BABY-SAT ADAM LANZA ABOUT TEN
YEARS AGO WHEN LANZA WAS 10 AND
KRAFT WAS 15.
HE DESCRIBES LANZA AS FOCUSED,
QUIET, INTROVERTED.
HE NEVER SAW EVIDENCE OF
VIOLENCE, KRAFT SAYS, BUT HE
SAYS LANZA DID THROW THE
OCCASIONAL TEMPER TANTRUM.
>> JUST GENERAL STUFF LIKE WE
HAD TO PUT HIM TO BED AND HE
WOULDN'T LIKE THAT OR STOP
WATCHING TV AND HE WOULDN'T LIKE
THAT.
NORMAL STUFF KIDS DO, BUT I
GUESS THE A10 YEARS OLD NORMAL
KIDS GET OUT OF THAT PHASE, AND
THAT WASN'T THE CASE FOR ADAM.
>> Reporter: KRAFT WAS ONLY A
YEAR OLDER THAN LANZA'S OLDER
BROTHER RYAN.
HIS MOTHER SAID TO LET RYAN DO
WHAT HE WANTED.
BUT AS FOR ADAM.
>> NANCY ASKED ME TO ALWAYS BE
WITH HIM IN THE ROOM NO MATTER
WHAT.
DON'T GO TO THE BATHROOM.
DON'T EVER LEAVE HIM WITHOUT
SUPERVISION.
>> Reporter: KRAFT SAYS ADAM HAD
A CONTENTIOUS RELATIONSHIP WITH
THE MOTHER NANCY.
SHE'D SPLIT WITH THE BOY'S
FATHER, PETER LANZA, WHO'S
DESCRIBED AS THE JOB NETWORKING
SITE LINKED IN AS TAX DIRECTOR
AT GE FINANCIAL SERVICES.
BUT KRAFT SAYS NANCY LANZA WAS
AN ENGAGED MOTHER, ALWAYS
SETTING UP PLAY DATES FOR HER
TWO SONS AND TAKING PART IN
NEIGHBORHOOD ACTIVITIES.
NANCY LANZA ENJOYED GARDENING
AND HAD TAKEN TIME OFF FROM A
JOB IN FINANCE.
>> JUST LIKE ANYBODY ELSE IN
THIS NEIGHBORHOOD.
DECORATE THE HOUSE, AND THE
HOUSE WAS ALWAYS PRISTINE.
I MEAN, SHE WAS JUST LIKE ANY
OTHER HOUSEWIFE.
>> Reporter: BUT LIKE HER SON,
THERE ARE GAPS IN NANCY LANZA'S
STORY THAT STILL NEED TO BE
FILLED IN.
SHE OWNED THE WEAPONS THAT ADAM
LANZA USED IN THE KILLINGS,
INCLUDING A SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE,
ACCORDING TO A LAW ENFORCEMENT
SOURCE, AND IT'S NOT CLEAR WHY
SHE PURCHASED THEM.
BRIAN TODD, CNN, WASHINGTON.
>> ALL RIGHT, BRIAN.
WE'RE STILL AWAITING THAT NEWS
CONFERENCE FROM NEWTOWN
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE, EXPECTED
TO BRIEF REPORTERS AT ANY
MOMENT.
YOU SEE THE PRODUCERS AND
REPORTERS THERE AND THE
MICROPHONES SET UP.
WE'LL BRING THAT TO YOU WHEN WE
GET IT HERE LIVE ON CNN.
WE'RE BACK IN A MOMENT.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH A SELECT TERRAIN DIAL
THAT ADJUSTS THE JEEP
GRAND CHEROKEE'S PERFORMANCE
FOR SPECIFIC WEATHER
AND ROAD CONDITIONS...
♪
...EVEN HEAVY SNOWSTORMS...
WON'T KEEP YOU
FROM GETTING TO WORK.
OUR APOLOGIES.
♪
to the number 1 club
in the world.
The potential of
Manchester United unlocked.
NYSE Euronext.
Unlocking the world's potential.
>>> NOW IS YOUR CHANCE TO TALK
BACK ON ONE OF THE BIG STORIES
FOR THE DAY.
THE QUESTION THIS MORNING, WHAT
CAN BE DONE TO PREVENT ANOTHER
NEWTOWN?
THAT'S A TOUGH QUESTION,
SOMETHING THAT REQUIRES LOTS OF
DISCUSSION, SOMETHING THAT SEEMS
IMPOSSIBLE WHEN IT COMES TO GUN
VIOLENCE.
AS THE PRESIDENT SAYS, WHAT
CHOICE DO WE HAVE?
THE BLAME GAME HAS ALREADY
BEGUN.
MIKE HUCKABEE, PASTOR AND FOX
NEWS HOST, SAYS OUR GODLESS
SCHOOLS ARE TO BLAME.
>> WE ASK WHY THERE'S VIOLENCE
IN SCHOOLS, ABOUT YOU WE'VE
SYSTEMATICALLY REMOVED GOD FROM
SCHOOLS.
SHOULD WE BE SURPRISED THAT
SCHOOLS HAVE BECOME A PLACE OF
CARNAGE?
WE'VE MADE IT A PLACE WHERE WE
DON'T WANT TO TALK ABOUT
ETERNITY, LIFE, WHAT
RESPONSIBILITY MEANS.
>> CNN CONTRIBUTOR AND TEA PARTY
SUPPORTER ERIC ERICKSON SAYS IN
HIS COLUMN TODAY SINGLE PARENT
HOMES LEAD TO VIOLENCE.
MANY ARE ALSO BLAMING VIOLENT
VIDEO GAMES AND MOVIES.
AFTER ALL, 11 VIOLENT MOVIES ARE
NOW IN THE THEATERS JUST ONE
WEEK BEFORE CHRISTMAS, THE DAY
WE CELEBRATE CHRIST'S BIRTH.
>> I AM SIMPLY A CUSTOMER TRYING
TO CONDUCT A TRANSACTION.
>> LAST CHANCE, FANCY PANTS.
>> VERY WELL.
[ GUNSHOT ]
>> INCLUDING QUENTIN TARANTINO'S
MOVIE "JANGO UNCHAINED."
>> IT'S JUST A HORRIBLE TRAGEDY.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO SAY ABOUT
IT?
IT'S HORRIBLE.
BUT, YEAH, AT THE SAME TIME, NO,
I DON'T THINK IT HAS ANYTHING TO
DO WITH THAT.
THIS HAS GONE BACK ALL THE WAY
DOWN TO SHAKESPEARE'S DAYS, WHEN
THERE'S VIOLENCE IN THE STREET.
THE CRY BECOMES BLAME THE PLAY
MAKERS.
I ACTUALLY -- I THINK THAT'S A
VERY FASCILE ARGUMENT TO PIN ON
SOMETHING THAT'S A REAL LIFE
TRAGEDY.
>> REPUBLICAN LAW MAKER BILLY
GOMER SAYS IT'S TOO FEW GUNS.
IF THE PRINCIPAL HAD HAD A GUN,
SHE COULD HAVE TAKEN OUT THE
SHOOTER AND PREVENTED A RAMPAGE.
OR MAYBE THERE'S TOO MANY GUNS.
SENATOR DIANNE FEINSTEIN PLANS
TO INTRODUCE LEGISLATION TO STOP
ASSAULT WEAPONS.
THE TALK BACK QUESTION FOR YOU
TODAY, WHAT CAN BE DONE TO
PREVENT ANOTHER NEWTOWN?
FACEBOOK.COM/CAROLCNN.
YOUR RESPONSES LATER THIS HOUR.
OF COURSE, WE'RE STILL WAITING
FOR THAT NEWS CONFERENCE TO
BEGIN IN NEWTOWN.
WE'RE EXPECTING LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE TO BE BEHIND THE
MICROPHONES AT ANY MOMENT NOW.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS KAREN AND JEREMIAH.
THEY DON'T KNOW IT YET,
BUT THEY'RE GONNA FALL IN LOVE,
GET MARRIED,
HAVE A COUPLE OF KIDS,
[ children laughing ]
MOVE TO THE COUNTRY,
AND LIVE A LONG, HAPPY LIFE
TOGETHER
WHERE THEY ALMOST NEVER FIGHT
ABOUT MONEY.
[ dog barks ]
BECAUSE RIGHT AFTER
THEY GET MARRIED,
THEY'LL FIND
SOME RETIREMENT PEOPLE
WHO ARE PAID ON SALARY,
NOT COMMISSION.
THEY'LL GET
STRAIGHTFORWARD GUIDANCE
AND BE ABLE TO FOCUS ON OTHER
THINGS, LIKE EACH OTHER,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
>>> GOOD MORNING.
THANKS SO MUCH FOR JOINING US
THIS MORNING.
I'M CAROL COSTELLO IN ATLANTA.
WITH ME TODAY, DON LEMON IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> GOOD MORNING TO YOU, CAROL.
WE'RE STILL AWAITING THE NEWS
CONFERENCE FROM NEWTOWN.
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE EXPECTED
TO BRIEF REPORTERS AT ANY MOMENT
NOW.
YOU SEE THEY'RE GETTING READY.
WE'LL CARRY THAT FOR YOU LIVE
RIGHT HERE ON CNN.
FOR NOW WE'LL GIVE YOU THE
LATEST ON THE SHOOTING AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THIS AFTERNOON 6-YEAR-OLDS JACK
PINTO AND NOAH POZNER WILL BE
THE FIRST OF THE 27 VICTIMS LAID
TO REST.
AND WE'RE ALSO LEARNING MORE
ABOUT THE REMARKABLE ACTS OF
HEROISM.
ONE TEACHER, ANN MARIE MURPHY,
SHE DIED WHILE SHIELDING
STUDENTS WITH HER BODY.
ANOTHER READ TO HER KIDS TO
DISTRACT THEM FROM GUNSHOTS
EXPLODING OUTSIDE THE ROOM.
AND LAST NIGHT PRESIDENT BARACK
OBAMA MET WITH THE FAMILIES OF
THOSE KILLED.
HE VOWED TO PREVENT ANOTHER
MASSACRE AND CALLED FOR A
NATIONAL DISCUSSION ON GUN
VIOLENCE.
>>I ITRIGHT NOW WE WANT TO CONTE
THE DISCUSSION WE STARTED WITH
TALK BACK.
WHAT CAN WE DO TO PREVENT
ANOTHER NEWTOWN?
IT'S NOT A DEMOCRATIC OR
REPUBLICAN PROBLEM BECAUSE WE'RE
ALL SUBJECT TO GUN VIOLENCE.
BUT MERELY SAYING WE NEED GUN
CONTROL IS TOO SIMPLISTIC.
WE HAVE MANY OTHER PROBLEMS.
LET'S BRING IN CNN CONTRIBUTOR
WILL CAIN.
I'M GOING TO HAVE TO INTERRUPT
YOU GUYS.
WE'RE GOING BACK TO NEWTOWN
BECAUSE THE NEWS CONFERENCE JUST
STARTED.
LIEUTENANT VANCE.
>> WE'D LIKE TO DELIVER TO YOU A
MESSAGE FROM THE SUPERINTENDENT
OF SCHOOLS RELATIVE TO
EDUCATIONAL PROCESS HERE IN THE
TOWN.
WE'LL START OFF WITH THE
LIEUTENANT ABOUT THE SCHOOLS
RIGHT NOW.
>> GOOD MORNING.
AS YOU KNOW, THE HEALING IS
STILL GOING ON.
THE SCHOOLS ARE WORKING VERY
CLOSELY WITH ALL THE FACULTY,
STUDENTS, AND PARENTS TO TRY TO
BE RESPECTFUL AND RESUME WHAT
NORMALCY WE CAN AFTER A TRAGEDY
SUCH AS THIS.
ALL THE FACULTY IS MEETING TODAY
AT NEWTOWN HIGH SCHOOL TO TRY TO
PLAN FURTHER ON HOW TO HANDLE IT
BEST AND ADDRESS THE NEEDS OF
THE STUDENTS AND FACULTY
INVOLVED IN THIS HORRENDOUS,
HORRENDOUS TRAGEDY.
THERE WILL BE NO SCHOOL TODAY.
THE PLAN IS TO TRY TO RESUME
NORMALCY FOR SCHOOL CLASSES
TOMORROW, EXCEPT FOR THOSE
MEMBERS OF THE SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL.
THEY WILL BE EXCUSED, OF COURSE,
UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE, AND
THEY'RE DEVELOPING PLANS ON HOW
TO BEST HANDLE THAT AS WE SPEAK.
>> THANK YOU, LIEUTENANT.
WE'RE CONTINUING THE LINE OF
COMMUNICATION WITH THE TROOPERS
AND OFFICERS ASSIGNED TO THE
FAMILIES AS WE BEGIN THE
SERVICES.
ADDITIONAL TROOPERS HAVE BEEN
ASSIGNED TO WORK EACH ONE OF THE
FUNERAL SERVICES WITH LOCAL
OFFICERS AND OTHER POLICE
PARTNERS.
WE'RE ASKING THE MEDIA AGAIN, AT
THE FAMILIES' REQUEST, TO PLEASE
RESPECT THEIR PRIVACY AS THEY GO
THROUGH THIS EXTREMELY DIFFICULT
TIME.
AS I STATED, STATE POLICE MAJOR
CRIMES DETECTIVES HAVE BEEN
WORKING 24 HOURS A DAY SINCE
THIS TRAGEDY OCCURRED AND WILL
CONTINUE TO DO SO INDEFINITELY
AS THEY CONTINUE TO ANSWER
QUESTIONS SURROUNDING THIS
TRAGEDY AND HOW AND WHY IT
OCCURRED.
THEY'RE CONTINUING TO INTERVIEW
WITNESSES, AS I'VE STATED
PREVIOUSLY, AND I CANNOT
OVERSTATE THERE ARE MANY, MANY
WITNESSES THAT NEED TO BE
INTERVIEWED.
WE WILL NOT STOP UNTIL WE'VE
INTERVIEWED EVERY LAST ONE OF
THEM.
WE ARE HOLDING BOTH CRIME
SCENES, THE SCHOOL AND THE
SECONDARY CRIME SCENE,
INDEFINITELY.
WE'VE SEIZED IT UNDER SEARCH
WARRANTS, AND WE'RE GOING TO
HOLD THOSE LOCATIONS UNTIL WE'VE
COMPLETED OUR WORK AND WE FEEL
IT IS APPROPRIATE TO LET THEM
GO.
SO AS NOT TO READ ANYTHING INTO
THAT, IT IS COMMON PRACTICE TO
DO THAT, TO HOLD ON TO THE CRIME
SCENE AS LONG AS IT'S NEEDED FOR
INVESTIGATORY PURPOSES.
WE HAD BEGUN PROCESSING THE
EVIDENCE, ANALYZING THE
EVIDENCE.
AS I STATED YESTERDAY, JUST TO
USE AN EXAMPLE, THE WEAPONRY,
EVERY SINGLE FACET OF THE
WEAPONS WILL BE ANALYZED.
EVERY SINGLE ROUND OF AMMUNITION
WILL BE LOOKED AT AND EXAMINED
FOR ANY KIND OF PHYSICAL
EVIDENCE.
I ALLUDED YESTERDAY TO THE
VOLUME OF ROUNDS, FOR EXAMPLE,
THAT, IN FACT, WERE SEIZED AND
RECOVERED.
EACH SINGULAR ROUND WILL BE
EXAMINED.
IT GIVES YOU AN IDEA OF THE
PAINSTAKING LENGTH OF THAT
PROCESS.
ALL THE EVIDENCE WILL BE
PROCESSED.
WE'LL CONTINUE TO ANALYZE EVERY
SINGLE PIECE, AND, AGAIN, I
CANNOT DETAIL THE CONTENT OF ANY
EVIDENCE OR EVEN WHAT THAT
EVIDENCE IS FOR PUBLIC
CONSUMPTION.
I WANT TO RESTATE AGAIN, THANK
YOU FOR HELPING US IN THIS, BUT
ANY THREATS, ANY INFORMATION
INTENDED TO MISLEAD
INVESTIGATORS IN THIS CASE WILL,
IN FACT, BE COMPLETELY AND
THOROUGHLY INVESTIGATED, AND IF
APPROPRIATE, PROSECUTED IF
ANYONE ATTEMPTS TO THREATEN OR
MISLEAD THIS INVESTIGATION.
AS YOU KNOW, THERE WERE A COUPLE
YESTERDAY, AND THOSE TOO ARE
ACTIVE CRIMINAL INVESTIGATIONS.
TEAMS OF STATE POLICE DETECTIVES
AND NEWTOWN DETECTIVES HAVE BEEN
ASSIGNED TO INVESTIGATE THOSE AS
ANCILLARY CRIMINAL CASES, IF YOU
WILL.
THE CRISIS TEAMS ARE STILL IN
PLACE.
I WANT TO GIVE YOU THAT PHONE
NUMBER AGAIN.
THERE ARE MANY PEOPLE IN THE
TOWN, AND THIS PHONE LINE IS
OPEN TO ANYONE, ANYONE WHO NEEDS
TO DISCUSS ANYTHING OR NEEDS
SUPPORT FROM PROFESSIONALS.
THEY'RE STAFFING THIS LINE FROM
THE HOSPITAL.
THE NUMBER IS 203-270-4283.
AT THIS TIME, I WILL ENTERTAIN
SOME QUESTIONS.
AGAIN, PLEASE KEEP IN MIND THAT
THERE ARE CERTAIN AREAS THAT WE
JUST CANNOT GO DOWN AT THIS
POINT IN TIME.
YES, MA'AM?
>> RICHFIELD SCHOOLS ARE
CURRENTLY UNDER LOCKDOWN.
IS IT ALL RELATED TO SANDY HOOK?
>> WHAT I'LL DO IS I'LL ADDRESS
THAT.
I'M AWARE OF THAT SITUATION IN
THE TOWN OF RICHFIELD.
THE LOCAL POLICE DEPARTMENT IS
HANDLING THAT SITUATION.
THERE'S A REPORT OF A SUSPICIOUS
PERSON THAT MAY, IN FACT, BE
ARMED.
WE'RE NOT SURE WHAT THE
SITUATION IS.
WE SENT APPROPRIATE PERSONNEL IN
THAT DIRECTION TO ASSIST
RICHFIELD, BUT RICHFIELD IS
HANDLING THAT SITUATION.
THERE'S BEEN NO UPDATES OTHER
THAN THAT.
>> DO THE SCHOOLS FEEL SAFE
RIGHT NOW?
>> THE SCHOOLS, AGAIN, ARE SAFE
WITH THE RIDGEFIELD OFFICERS AND
RIDGEFIELD POLICE DEPARTMENT
WITH THAT.
>> YOU'RE SAYING YOU'RE
INTERVIEWING EVERY WITNESS.
OBVIOUSLY, THAT INCLUDES
CHILDREN.
CAN YOU TALK ABOUT HOW YOU'RE
HANDLING THAT?
>> I DON'T WANT TO GET INTO
DETAIL.
IT'S A VERY, VERY TENDER, TENDER
ISSUE.
I CAN TELL YOU THAT ANY
INTERVIEWS WITH ANY CHILDREN
WILL BE DONE WITH PROFESSIONALS,
WITH PARENTS, AND WITH
INVESTIGATORS, AS APPROPRIATE.
THE INVESTIGATORS WILL DETERMINE
HOW, WHEN, WHERE, AND WHY WE'LL
DO THIS.
AGAIN, UNDERSTAND WE WILL HANDLE
THAT EXTREMELY DELICATELY WHEN
THE TIME ARISES.
>> LIEUTENANT, HAVE YOU HAD ANY
MEDICAL OR MENTAL HEALTH
PROFESSIONALS COME FORWARD TO
SAY WHETHER THEY WERE TREATING
ADAM LANZA?
IF THERE ARE ANY OUT THERE WITH
SUCH INFORMATION, WOULD YOU ASK
THEM TO COME FORWARD?
>> CERTAINLY, WE WOULD ENCOURAGE
ANYONE WITH ANY INFORMATION TO
COME FORWARD THAT CAN ASSIST US
IN THIS INVESTIGATION.
WHEN I TALKED ABOUT THE WEAPONRY
AND THE HISTORICAL ANALYSIS, ALL
THE WEAPONRY INVOLVED, THE SAME
THING HOLDS TRUE WITH THE
SUSPECT.
WE WILL GO BACK TO THE DATE OF
BIRTH.
WE WILL CONTINUE ON THROUGH.
WE WILL ANSWER EVERY SINGLE
QUESTION DETERMINING ANY KIND OF
MEDICAL CONDITION, ANY KIND OF
ISSUE WHATSOEVER THAT MAY HAVE
BEEN INVOLVED IN.
I AM NOT AT LIBERTY TO DISCUSS
MEDICAL CONTENT.
I'M NOT AT LIBERTY TO DISCUSS
ANY OF THE INFORMATION SO FAR
UNCOUGHED, BU
UNCOVERED, BUT SUFFICE IT TO
SAY, I WANT TO SAY WE WILL COVER
EVERY SINGLE FACET.
>> THERE ARE REPORTS THAT LAW
ENFORCEMENT WAS CONCERNED ABOUT
ADAM LANZA PREVIOUS TO THIS.
DO YOU HAVE ANY INSIGHT INTO
THAT?
>> NO.
WE'VE BEEN IN DISCUSSIONS WITH
NEWTOWN POLICE, AND THERE WAS NO
PREVIOUS CONTACT OR CONCERNS
PRIOR TO THIS TRAGIC EVENT.
YES, SIR.
>> CAN YOU TELL US MORE DETAIL
ON HOW HE PROCEEDED TO GET IN
THE SCHOOL AND WHAT HE DID ONCE
INSIDE.
>> I CAN'T DO THAT.
IT'S TOO DIFFICULT TO DISCUSS.
I'M NOT GOING TO LIE TO YOU,
I CAN TELL YOU, AS I'VE BEEN
TELLING YOU, THE SUSPECT FORCED
HIS WAY INTO THE SCHOOL BEFORE
AND AS HE BEGAN TO TAKE HUMAN
LIFE THEREIN.
I SIMPLY DON'T WANT TO -- AND
IT'S NOT APPROPRIATE FOR US TO
GO ANY FURTHER WITH THAT.
YES, MA'AM.
>> ARE OFFICERS STILL TALKING TO
GUN SHOPS AND GUN RANGES TO FIND
OUT INFORMATION ABOUT WHETHER
LANZA TRIED TO POSSESS OTHER
FIREARMS.
>> GOOD QUESTION.
WE'RE NOT ONLY CHECKING THE
WEAPONRY, BUT ATF IS WORKING
WITH US.
NEWTOWN IS WORKING WITH US.
OTHER AGENCIES WORKING WITH US
SEARCHING EVERY DATABASE, EVERY
RECORD, SEARCHING EVERYTHING WE
CAN POSSIBLY UNCOVER.
AGAIN, IF ANYONE HAD ANY CONTACT
WITH THE SUSPECT AT ANY RANGE OR
ANY LOCATION, WE WANT TO TALK TO
THEM IF WE HAVEN'T REACHED THEM
YET.
YES, SIR?
>> HAS ANY PROGRESS BEEN MADE IN
TRYING TO ASCERTAIN SOME
INFORMATION FROM THE COMPUTERS
YOU FOUND SMASHED.
>> I CAN TELL THAW OUR COMPUTER
CRIMES UNIT, WORKING WITH THE
FORENSIC LABORATORY, ARE WORKING
NONSTOP EXAMINING ANY EVIDENCE
THAT WAS SEIZED AT ANY LOCATION,
LITERALLY.
WHETHER IT BE CELL PHONES,
COMPUTERS.
AND I'M NOT NAMING ANYTHING THAT
WAS SEIZED.
I'M SAYING ALL THAT ELECTRONIC
EVIDENCE WILL, IN FACT, BE
ANALYZED.
WE CERTAINLY WILL DISSECT IT, IF
YOU WILL.
>> DID ADAM LEAVE ANY EVIDENCE
AT THE HOME?
>> I CAN'T DISCUSS THE EVIDENCE.
>> IS THERE A SEPARATE SURVIVOR?
REPORTS THAT THERE ARE TWO
SURVIVORS.
>> YES, THERE ARE TWO ADULTS
THAT WERE INJURED IN THE
FACILITY, IN THE SCHOOL, THAT
SUFFERED GUNSHOT WOUNDS AND ARE
RECOVERING.
>> WHY DID HE HAVE HIS BROTHER'S
I.D.?
>> I DON'T HAVE ANY INFORMATION
ABOUT WHAT HE WAS CARRYING AT
ALL.
>> NO INFORMATION ABOUT HOW HE
GOT HIS BROTHER'S I.D.?
>> NO INFORMATION ABOUT WHAT HE
WAS CARRYING AT ALL.
>> WAS THERE A SURVEILLANCE
SYSTEM INSIDE THAT SCHOOL?
>> I'M NOT AWARE OF THAT.
I'M SORRY.
I DON'T HAVE THAT INFORMATION.
>> ABOUT WHAT SHOULD HAPPEN WITH
THE SCHOOL AFTER IT'S NO LONGER
A CRIME SCENE?
>> THAT WILL A TOWN DECISION,
THE TOWN LEADERS.
AGAIN, WE ARE POSSESSING THAT
SCHOOL.
WE ARE HOLDING THAT SCHOOL AS A
CRIME SCENE INDEFINITELY.
AND I CAN'T EVEN TELL YOU WHAT
THAT MEANS.
I DON'T KNOW HOW LONG THAT WILL
BE.
I'M SUSPECTING MONTHS.
AT THAT TIME, IT'S UP TO THE
TOWN OFFICIALS TO DETERMINE
EXACTLY WHAT'S APPROPRIATE WITH
THAT FACILITY AND WITH THAT
BUILDING.
YES, SIR?
>> CAN YOU TALK ABOUT HOW THE
TWO SURVIVORS ARE HELPING AT ALL
IF IN THIS INVESTIGATION?
>> WE PROVIDED THE SURVIVORS
WITH THE SAME CONDUIT WE
PROVIDED ALL THE OTHER VICTIMS
IN THIS CASE, AND THAT IS LAW
ENFORCEMENT ESCORT, IF YOU WILL.
OUR INVESTIGATORS WILL, IN FACT,
SPEAK WITH THEM WHEN IT'S
MEDICALLY APPROPRIATE, AND
CERTAINLY THEY WILL SHED A GREAT
DEAL OF LIGHT ON THE FACTS AND
CIRCUMSTANCES OF THIS TRAGIC
INVESTIGATION THAT WE'RE
UNDERTAKING.
>> LIEUTENANT, WOULD YOU TALK
ABOUT THE TREMENDOUS AMOUNT OF
AMMUNITION THAT HE HAD WITH HIM.
YOU ALLUDED TO THAT YESTERDAY.
THE GOVERNOR TALKED ABOUT THAT
YESTERDAY AS WELL.
DO YOU NOW BELIEVE THAT HE HAD
MUCH WIDER INTENTIONS INSIDE
THAT SCHOOL THAT WERE THWARTED
BECAUSE OF THE EFFORTS OF LAW
ENFORCEMENT?
>> I THINK WHAT'S IMPORTANT IS
THAT I CAN'T SPECULATE WHAT
WOULD HAVE OCCURRED.
THAT WOULD BE WRONG ON MY PART.
I CAN TELL YOU THAT THE FACULTY,
STAFF IN THAT SCHOOL DID
EVERYTHING THAT THEY POSSIBLY
COULD TO PROTECT THOSE CHILDREN.
I CAN TELL YOU THAT THE FIRST
RESPONDERS THAT GOT TO THAT
SCENE WITH THE ACTIVE SHOOTER
TEAM ENTERED THAT SCHOOL AND
SAVED MANY HUMAN LIVES, AND I
CAN TELL YOU IT BROKE OUR HEARTS
WE COULDN'T SAVE THEM ALL.
SO QUITE FRANKLY, THERE ARE THE
VICTIMS, THE FAMILIES IN THIS
SITUATION THAT REALLY ARE A
FOCUS OF OUR ATTENTION RIGHT
NOW.
WE'LL LEAVE THAT THERE, PLEASE.
>> IS THERE ANY ADDED POLICE
PRESENCE IN OTHER SCHOOLS AROUND
THIS STATE.
>> THAT'S WHAT I'VE DONE UNDER
THE LEADERSHIP OF THE GOVERNOR
AND THE EDUCATIONAL COMMISSIONER
AND LAW, ALL THE LOCAL
OFFICIALS.
MANY, MANY SCHOOLS ARE SHOWING
LAW ENFORCEMENT SUPPORT AND
SECURITY, AND I MUST STATE VERY
EMPHATICALLY, VERY EMPHATICALLY,
THAT IT IS NOT FUNNY.
IT IS NOT A JOKE.
IT IS NOT ACCEPTABLE FOR ANYONE
TO MAKE ANY KIND OF INNER THREAT
OR MAKE ANY STATEMENT RELATIVE
TO THE SECURITY AND THE
INDIVIDUAL SCHOOLS, RESPECT
WHAT'S OCCURRED HERE.
I WOULD ASK PEOPLE TO RESPECT
WHAT'S OCCURRED HERE, AND
CERTAINLY WE'RE GOING TO DO OUR
BEST TO ENSURE SECURITY
STATEWIDE.
LAW ENFORCEMENT WILL DO SO AS
WELL AS THE PROFESSIONALS AT
EACH AND EVERY EDUCATIONAL
INSTITUTION IN CONNECTICUT.
WHAT I'D LIKE TO DO NOW IS TELL
YOU THAT I DON'T WANT TO KEEP
COMING.
WE'LL COME HERE EVERY DAY.
LIEUTENANT AND I COME HERE EVERY
DAY IF IT'S NECESSARY.
I DON'T WANT TO COME AND JUST
TELL YOU EVERYTHING'S UNDER
INVESTIGATION.
OUR NEXT BRIEFING WE'LL HAVE
WILL PROBABLY BE ABOUT 12:00
NOON TODAY, JUST BEFORE 12:00
NOON IF WE CAN GET HERE TO BRING
YOU UP TO DATE WITH ANYTHING WE
HAVE.
BUT WE'RE GOING TO -- WE'RE
GOING TO START SCALING BACK THE
BRIEFINGS, AND WE'LL PUT
EVERYTHING THAT'S NECESSARY
APPLICABLE TO THIS INVESTIGATION
ON OUR WEBSITE.
WE TRULY BELIEVE THAT KEEPING
YOU HERE IS PROBABLY SOMEWHAT
COUNTERPRODUCTIVE.
I WOULD RESTATE AGAIN, PLEASE,
THE FAMILIES HAVE REQUESTED
PRIVACY DURING THE SERVICES, AND
I KNOW YOU FOLKS HAVE BEEN
GREAT.
I WOULD ASK YOU TO CONTINUE TO
DO SO.
WE'LL SEE YOU JUST BEFORE NOON.
THANK YOU.
>> CAN YOU GIVE US SOME NUMBERS
ON INVESTIGATORS AND STAFF
INVOLVED IN THIS INVESTIGATION.
>> I CAN TELL YOU SIGNIFICANT.
WELL OVER A COUPLE HUNDRED
TROOPERS AND DETECTIVES AND
LOCAL POLICE OFFICERS.
IN ADDITION TO LOCAL POLICE
OFFICERS, NEWTOWN POLICE,
FEDERAL AGENCIES, FEDERAL
AGENTS.
A TOTAL NUMBER, I WOULD JUST BE
GRASPING A NUMBER OUT OF THE SKY
LITERALLY.
>> LIEUTENANT VANCE FROM THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE.
YOU HEARD THAT HE SAID THERE'S
INCREASED SECURITY IN PART
PROVIDED BY THE EDUCATIONAL
SYSTEM OF CONNECTICUT AND IN
PART PROVIDED BY POLICE
DEPARTMENTS ACROSS THE STATE.
EXTRA SECURITY AT ALL OF THOSE
SCHOOLS, WHICH LEADS US BACK TO
OUR QUESTION.
HOW DO WE PREVENT ANOTHER
NEWTOWN?
FRONT AND CENTER, HOW DO WE
PROTECT OUR CHILDREN IN SCHOOLS
THESE DAYS?
SO LET'S BRING BACK OUR
CONTRIBUTORS.
WILL CAIN, L.Z. GRAN DER SODERS
DON LEMON.
L.Z., YOU HAD A VERY TOUCHING
COLUMN ABOUT HOW PARENTS CAN
KEEP THEIR CHILDREN SAFE.
WHAT CONCLUSION DID YOU COME TO?
>> SADLY, THE CONCLUSION I CAME
TO AS A PARENT WAS IT'S
VIRTUALLY IMPOSSIBLE TO ENSURE
THAT MY SON OR ANYONE'S CHILD
WILL BE PROTECTED FROM ANY HARM
THAT CAN HAPPEN ONCE THEY'RE OUT
OF OUR SIGHTS.
AS I WAS DROPPING MY SON OFF
THIS MORNING, I WATCHED HIM WALK
ALL THE WAY INTO THE BUILDING,
AND IT LITERALLY TOOK EVERY
EFFORT IN ME NOT TO GET OUT OF
THE CAR AND WALK HIM PERSONALLY
TO THE BUILDING, AND HE'S 16
YEARS OLD.
YOU KNOW, WHEN YOU SEE SOMETHING
LIKE THIS, YOU SEE THE LITTLE
LIVES THAT WERE TAKEN, I DON'T
KNOW HOW ANY PARENT CAN HAVE
PEACE WHEN THEIR CHILD IS NOT
NEAR THEM.
SO IT'S VERY, VERY DISTRESSING,
AND WE'RE REALLY HOPING THAT THE
CONVERSATIONS THAT HAVE BEGUN TO
HAPPEN THIS WEEKEND DON'T END
ONCE ALL THE FUNERALS HAVE BEEN
HELD.
THAT TRUE LEGISLATIVE POWER
COMES FROM THIS.
>> WE'LL SEE.
WILL, I'M GOING TO ASK YOU A
TOUGH QUESTION.
I KNOW AT LEAST TWO SCHOOL
DISTRICTS IN PITTSBURGH,
PENNSYLVANIA, HAVE GIVEN
SECURITY OFFICERS IN SCHOOLS
PERMISSION TO CARRY GUNS TODAY.
IS THAT THE ANSWER?
IS THAT HOW WE KEEP KIDS SAFE?
DO WE ARM SCHOOL SECURITY
GUARDS?
DO WE ARM THE PRINCIPALS?
>> CAROL, THAT DOESN'T -- FROM A
COMMON SENSE, INSTINCTUAL LEVEL,
NO, THAT DOESN'T RING AS
APPROPRIATE TO ME.
HERE'S THE DEAL.
JUST LIKE L.Z., I DROPPED MY SON
OFF AT SCHOOL THIS MORNING.
MY SON IS 5 YEARS OLD.
HE'S RIGHT IN THIS AGE RANGE.
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO ESCAPE THE
EMOTION OF THIS MOMENT.
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO LOOK AT THIS
IN STRICTLY RATIONAL TERMS.
THAT BEING SAID, I THINK THAT
OUR FOCUS ON GUNS, IT JUST --
IT'S TOO NARROW.
IT DOESN'T STAND UP TO CRITICAL
THOUGHT.
HERE'S THE DEAL, CAROL.
GUN VIOLENCE IS, QUITE HONESTLY,
IT'S DOWN FROM A PEAK IN THE
1990s.
AND YET THESE MASS KILLINGS ARE
UP.
SIX OF THE DEADLIEST 12 HAVE
HAPPENED SINCE 2007.
SO IF GUNS ARE SOMEWHAT
CONSTANT, WHAT IS THE
DETERMINING FACTOR?
WHAT HAS CHANGED?
WE MUST FIGURE OUT A WAY TO
ADDRESS MENTAL HEALTH, ANALYZE
MENTAL HEALTH.
SOMETHING HAS CHANGED IN OUR
COUNTRY IN THE LAST 40 YEARS.
THE PROCESS OF
DEINSTITUTIONALIZING MENTAL
HEALTH OR THE RISE IN
PSYCHOTROPIC DRUGS.
THIS SEEMS TO BE THE ONLY THING
THAT I CAN PINPOINT NOW THAT IS
THE DELINEATING FACTOR, AND
THAT'S WHERE WE MUST FOCUS.
>> LET'S HEAD TO NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AND DON LEMON, WHAT
ARE PEOPLE THERE SAYING?
>> LET ME -- LISTEN, FOR THE
PAST THREE DAYS, I HAVE BEEN ON
THE VERGE OF TEARS EVERY SECOND,
AND MOST OF THE PEOPLE HERE HAVE
BEEN CRYING 24 HOURS STRAIGHT.
YES, WE NEED TO ADDRESS MENTAL
HEALTH, BUT MENTAL HEALTH IN
THIS PARTICULAR ISSUE -- LET'S
NOT GET IT TWISTED -- IS A
SECONDARY ISSUE.
IF SOMEONE WHO HAS A MENTAL
ISSUE DID NOT HAVE ACCESS TO
GUNS THAT SHOULD ONLY BE
AVAILABLE IN WAR ZONES, WE WOULD
NOT BE DEALING WITH THIS.
WHO NEEDS A BULLET PIERCING,
ARMOR PIERCING BULLET TO GO
HUNTING?
WHO NEEDS AN ASSAULT RIFLE TO GO
YOU CAN'T EVEN USE THE PREY THAT
YOU KILL WITH AN ASSAULT RIFLE
IF YOU INDEED DO IT.
NO ONE NEEDS AN ASSAULT RIFLE TO
GO OUT AND SHOOT A DEER.
NO ONE NEEDS AN ASSAULT RIFLE
THAT'S CAPABLE OF SHOOTING 10,
20, 30 ROUNDS OFF AT A TIME TO
SHOOT A DUCK OR TO SHOOT QUAIL.
IT DOES NOT MAKE SENSE.
THE FIRST THING THAT WE NEED TO
DO, ACCORDING TO EVERYONE WHO IS
HERE, EVEN GUN ENTHUSIASTS, IS
TALK ABOUT WHAT WE'RE DOING WITH
ASSAULT RIFLES.
WHY SHOULD GUNS THAT SHOULD ONLY
BE AVAILABLE IN WAR ZONES, WHY
ARE THEY AVAILABLE TO PEOPLE WHO
ARE MENTALLY HEALTHY AND PEOPLE
WHO ARE NOT MENTALLY HEALTHY?
THAT'S THE ISSUE THAT WE NEED TO
DEAL WITH.
SO TO SAY THAT GUN VIOLENCE IS
DOWN DOES NOT MAKE SENSE.
TO ME, IT'S INSULTING TO
EVERYONE WHO LOST A LOVED ONE
HERE AND WHO WAS DEALING WITH
THAT.
IT DOESN'T MATTER IF GUN
VIOLENCE IS DOWN.
20 CHILDREN ARE DEAD HERE AND 6
ADULTS ARE DEAD, AND THE MOTHER
OF A PERSON WHO WAS NOT
MENTALLY -- WHO IS MENTALLY
CHALLENGED IN SOME WAY IS DEAD.
SO TO SAY THAT GUN VIOLENCE IS
DOWN -- WE NEED TO TALK ABOUT
MENTAL HEALTH, YES.
MENTAL HEALTH IS A SECONDARY
ISSUE.
WE NEED TO GET GUNS AND BULLETS
AND AUTOMATIC WEAPONS OFF THE
STREETS.
THEY SHOULD ONLY BE AVAILABLE TO
POLICE OFFICERS AND TO HUNT AL
QAEDA AND THE TALIBAN AND NOT
HUNTCHILDREN.
>> WE ARE GOING TO HAVE TO WRAP
THIS UP.
THANKS SO MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> QUICK CHECK ON SOME OF THE
STORIES MAKING NEWS TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN IT COMES TO
THE FINANCIAL OBSTACLES
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAND.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
>>> MORE COVERAGE ON THE
CONNECTICUT SHOOTINGS IN JUST A
MINUTE.
FIRST A LOOK AT OTHER TOP
STORIES.
INDEPENDENT REVIE BOARD WILL
PRESENT A REPORT TO THE STATE
DEPARTMENT ON BENGHAZI.
THE MOST DETAILED EXPLANATION
YET FROM SEPTEMBER 11.
A GUNMAN ESCAPED AFTER SHOOTING
AND I WILL KILLING TWO POLICE
OFFICERS IN TOPEKA, KANSAS.
THE POLICE RESPONDED TO A REPORT
OF SUSPICIOUS VEHICLE OUTSIDE OF
A GROCERY STORE LAST NIGHT.
>>> FISCAL CLIFF NEGOTIATION
TALK, HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER
OFFERED TO EXTEND THE DEBT LIMIT
FOR A YEAR.
REPUBLICANS HAVE BEEN OPPOSED TO
RAISING THE BORROWING CAP.
BOEHNER PROPOSED HIGHER TAX
RATES ON THE WEALTHIEST
AMERICANS IN ORDER TO REACH A
DEAL.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS DECEMBER, REMEMBER --
YOU CAN STAY IN
AND LIKE SOMETHING...
OR YOU CAN GET OUT THERE
AND ACTUALLY LIKE SOMETHING.
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
UP HIGH!
OK. DON'T YOU HAVE
ANY USEFULL APPS ON THAT THING?
WHO DO YOU THINK I AM,
Quicken Loans?
♪
AT Quicken Loans,
OUR AMAZINGLY USEFUL
MORTGAGE CALCULATOR APP
ALLOWS YOU TO QUICKLY CALCULATE
YOUR MORTGAGE PAYMENT
BASED ON TODAY'S INCREDIBLY LOW
INTEREST RATES...
RIGHT FROM YOUR IPHONE
OR ANDROID SMARTPHONE.
ONE MORE WAY Quicken Loans
IS ENGINEERED TO AMAZE.
♪
>>> THE TALK BACK QUESTION TODAY
IS A TOUGH ONE.
WHAT CAN BE DONE TO PREVENT
ANOTHER NEWTOWN?
ENCOURAGE THE FAMILY SETTING
THAT'S WASHED AWAY IN OUR
SOCIETY.
A LOVING HOME IS THE BEST THING
YOU CAN DO FOR A CHILD.
GOD BELONGS IN CHURCH NOT IN
PUBLIC SCHOOLS.
TWO, MENTAL HEALTH PROFESSIONALS
SHOULD BE AVAILABLE TO EVERYONE.
LEE, THERE SHOULD BE MORE
CONTROL OVER WHO HAS ASALT-TYPE
WEAPONS.
FIRST WE STOP RIDING A STAGE FOR
MANIPULATORS THAT DISTRACT PLUS
DECISIVE LEGISLATIVE ACTION TO
PROTECT OUR CHILDREN.
THIS IS NOT A GUN CONTROL ISSUE.
GUNS DON'T KILL PEOPLE.
PEOPLE KILL PEOPLE.
THIS NEEDS TO BE ABOUT MENTAL
ILLNESS AND WHAT OUR COUNTRY CAN
DO TO KEEP THAT UNDER CONTROL.
A LOT COULD BE DONE BUT NOTHING
WILL BE DONE.
BECAUSE OF THE GUN LOBBY.
THE NRA AND THE REPUBLICANS WHO
ARE SUPPORTED BY THESE GROUPS.
THEY ENABLE MASS MURDERERS.
BAN GUNS AND CRIMINALS OR PEOPLE
WITH INTENT ON KILLING OTHERS
WILL HAVE EASY ACCESS TO GUNS IN
THE BLACK MARKET.
BAN GUNS AND YOU LEAVE ME, LA  A
LAW-ABIDING CITIZEN DEFENSELESS.
CUSTOMER ERIN SWENSON
BOUGHT FROM US ONLINE TODAY.
SO, I'M HAPPY.
SALES GO UP... I'M HAPPY.
IT WENT OUT TODAY... I'M HAPPY.
WHAT IF SHE'S NOT HOME?
(TOGETHER)
SHE WON'T BE HAPPY.
USE UPS! SHE CAN GET
A TEXT ALERT, REROUTE...
EVEN RESCHEDULE HER PACKAGE.
IT'S UPS MY CHOICE.
ARE YOU HAPPY?
I'M HAPPY.
HAPPY.
(TOGETHER)
I LOVE LOGISTICS.
>>> HAPPENING NOW.
HOW CAN WE PREVENT ANOTHER
NEWTOWN?
GUN CONTROL?
BETTER MENTAL HEALTH SERVICES?
PUTTING GOD BACK IN OUR SCHOOLS?
WE WILL TALK WITH CONNECTICUT
SENATOR JOE LIEBERMAN.
INVESTIGATORS DIG IMPORTANCES.
WHO WAS THE MAN POLICE SAY WAS
BEHIND THESE DEADLY SHOOTINGS?
THIS TRAGEDY COULD HAVE BEEN, IF
YOU CAN BELIEVE IT, A LOT WORSE
IF NOT FOR THE TEACHERS AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THEY ARE BEING CALLED HEROES FOR
THEIR ACTION WHEN THE SHOOTINGS
BEGAN.
YOU WILL HEAR FROM ONE OF THEM.
A SPECIAL EDITION OF "NEWSROOM"
STARTS NOW.
♪
>>> GOOD MORNING.
THANK FOR BEING WITH US.
I'M CAROL COSTELLO IN ATLANTA.
WITH ME TODAY, DON LEMON,
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
GOOD MORNING.
>> GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
WE ARE GOING TO BEGIN THIS HOUR
WITH THE LATEST FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
MINUTES AGO POLICE HELD A
BRIEFING TO UPDATE REPORTERS ONE
TOPIC WRESTLING WITH THE
QUESTION OF WHEN OR EVEN IF KIDS
CAN RETURN TO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
>> THERE WILL BE NO SCHOOL
TODAY.
THE PLAN THE S TO TRY TO RESUME
NORMALCY FOR SCHOOL CLASSES
TOMORROW EXCEPT FOR THOSE
MEMBERS AT THE SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL.
THEY WILL BE EXCUSED, OF COURSE,
UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE.
THEY ARE DEVELOPING PLANS ON HOW
TO BEST HANDLE THAT.
>> TODAY THE FIRST OF THE
FUNERALS GET UNDER WAY.
THIS AFTERNOON, 6-YEAR-OLDS,
JACK PINTO, AND NOAH POZNER WILL
BE THE FIRST OF THE VICTIM TO BE
LAID TO REST.
ONE TEACHER, ANNE MARIE MURPHY
DIED WHILE SHIELDING STUDENTS
WITH HER BODY.
ANOTHER READ TO HER KIDS TO
DISTRACT THEM FROM THE GUNSHOTS
EXPLODING OUTSIDE OF THEIR ROOM.
AND LAST NIGHT IN NEWTOWN
PRESIDENT OBAMA MET WITH
SURVIVORS AND FAMILIES OF THOSE
KILLED AND VOWED TO PREVENT
ANOTHER MASSACRE AND CALL FOR A
NATIONAL DISCUSSION ON GUN
VIOLENCE.
MORE ON THE GUN CONTROL DEBATE
IN JUST A MOMENT.
FIRST THE PRESIDENT'S MESSAGE TO
A COMMUNITY IN ANGUISH.
HERE ARE SOME OF THE COMMENTS
FROM LAST NIGHT'S VIGIL.
>> I AM VERY MINDFUL THAT MERE
WORDS CANNOT MATCH THE DEPTHS OF
YOUR SORROW NOR CAN THEY HEAL
YOUR WOUNDED HEARTS.
I CAN ONLY HOPE IT HELPS FOR YOU
TO KNOW THAT YOU ARE NOT ALONE
IN YOUR GRIEF.
THAT OUR WORLD, TOO, HAS BEEN
TORN APART.
THAT ALL ACROSS THIS LAND OF
OURS, WE HAVE WEPT WITH YOU.
WE PULLED OUR CHILDREN TIGHT.
AND YOU MUST KNOW THAT WHATEVER
MEASURE OF COMFORT WE CAN
PROVIDE, WE WILL PROVIDE.
WHATEVER PORTION OF SADNESS THAT
WE CAN SHARE WITH YOU TO EASE
THIS HEAVY LOAD, WE WILL GLADLY
BEAR IT.
NEWTOWN, YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
>> Reporter: WE ARE GOING TO BE
BACK HERE IN NEWTOWN IN JUST A
FEW MINUTES.
FOR NOW, I'M GOING TO HAND IT
BACK OVER TO CAROL WHO IS IN
ATLANTA.
I WATCHED IT HERE IN A TAVERN
NOT A DRY EYE IN THE HOUSE.
IT WAS SUCH A MOVING MEMORIAL
LAST NIGHT.
>> IT REALLY WAS.
THE PRESIDENT TALKED ABOUT DOING
SOMETHING.
HE SORT OF INTIMATED GUN CONTROL
WAS PART OF THAT SOMETHING.
HOW DID YOU TAKE THAT, DON?
>> Reporter: I THINK HE HAD SOME
VERY STRONG LANGUAGE ON GUN
LAWS.
I DON'T KNOW IF GUN CONTROL IS
THE RIGHT THING -- I THINK WHAT
THE PRESIDENT IS SAYING AND MOST
PEOPLE ARE SAYING, IT IS NOT
ABOUT TAKING AWAY ANYONE'S
SECOND AMENDMENT RIGHTS.
IT IS ABOUT HAVING A SENSIBLE,
NON-POLITICIZED CONVERSATION
ABOUT OUR GUN LAWS, TAKINGING A
SECOND LOOK AT THEM.
I THINK THAT'S APPROPRIATE AT
THIS POINT.
>> OKAY.
DON, AFTER WHAT HAPPENED IN
NEWTOWN, SCHOOLS ARE STRUGGLING
WITH GUN CONTROL.
GUNS IN GENERAL AND HOW TO KEEP
KIDS SAFE.
ONE WAY ARMED SCHOOL SECURITY
GUARDS.
ACCORDING TO THE PITTSBURGH
GAZETTE, AT LEAST WOULD
PITTSBURGH AREA SCHOOL DISTRICTS
WILL ALLOW ARMED GUARDS TO
PATROL THEIR SCHOOLS.
THE SUPERINTENDENT TOLD THE
PAPER, QUOTE, IT WAS OUR INTENT
TO DO THIS ANYWAY.
THE MUST HAVE TOWN SHOOTING
CAUSED US TO THINK ABOUT IT AND
WORK OVER THE WEEKEND TO
EXPEDITE THAT PROCESS.
GUN ADVOCATES ARE ALSO FOR IT.
>> I WISH TO GOD SHE HAD AN M-4
IN HER OFFICE LOCKED UP SO WHEN
SHE HEARD GUNFIRE PULLED IT OUT
AND DIDN'T HAVE TO LUNG
HEROICALLY WITH NOTHING IN HER
HANDS BUT TAKES HIM OUT.
>> HE MENTIONED AN M-4.
IF YOU ARE WONDERING WHAT AN M-4
IS, HERE IS A PICTURE OF IT.
AN ASSAULT RIFLE USED BY THE
U.S. MILITARY.
JOINING US NOW IS CONNECTICUT
SENATOR JOE LIEBERMAN.
GOOD MORNING, SENATOR.
>> GOOD MORNING, CAROL.
>> I'M JUST GOING CUT RIGHT TO
THE CHASE.
IS THAT THE ANSWER, SENATOR,
MORE GUNS?
>> I DON'T BELIEVE IT IS.
OBVIOUSLY SECURITY AT SCHOOL
BUILDINGS IS IMPORTANT.
BUT THIS -- AS THE PRESIDENT
SAID, VERY ELOQUENTLY LAST NIGHT
IS A VERY COMPLICATED PROBLEM.
BUT THE FACT THAT IT IS
COMPLICATED DOESN'T MEAN WE
CAN'T DOING IN ABOUT IT AND I
THOUGHT THE PRESIDENT ISSUED A
CALL TO NATIONAL ACTION PRECEDED
BY DISCUSSION WHEN HE SAID THAT
IT IS TIME FOR THESE TRAGEDIES
TO END.
I MEAN, CLEARLY PART OF IT HAS
TO BE -- TO MAKE IT HARDER TO --
FOR PEOPLE WHO SHOULDN'T HAVE
GUNS TO HAVE THEM.
AND TO KEEP SOME GUNS THAT ARE
MILITARY GUNS AND NOT HUNTING OR
SPORTS GUNS OUT OF THE HANDS OF
MOST PEOPLE IN OUR COUNTRY.
BUT IT IS MORE THAN IN A.
IT IS ABOUT BALANCE AND THE
CULTURE.
MENTAL HEALTH SERVICES.
IT IS ABOUT SPOTTING THESE KIDS
WHO FIT THE PROFILE, TROUBLED
YOUNG MEN, WHO EVERYBODY IN
HINDSIGHT SAYS I SHOULD HAVE
NOTICED THIS.
HOW WE MAKE SURE WE NOTICE IT
BEFORE THEY STRIKE AND GET THEM
HELP SO THAT -- SO NEVER STRIKE
AND HURT ANYBODY.
>> SENATOR, I THINK A LOT OF
PEOPLE OUT WILL THINK, YOU KNOW,
THESE TRAGEDIES HAPPEN.
WE HEAR BIG TALK FROM
POLITICIANS, WHAT THEY DON'T --
THEY DON'T HAVE THE POLITICAL
WILL OR COURAGE TO REALLY CHANGE
THINGS.
>> I DON'T BLAME PEOPLE FOR
THINKING THAT BECAUSE -- THAT'S
THE RECORD.
YOU KNOW.
THE LAST THING WE REALLY ADOPTED
A LAW ON GUNS, FOR INSTANCE, WAS
IN 1993 OR '94, THE BRADY ACT
NAMED AFTER JIM BRADY, PRESIDENT
REAGAN'S PRESS SECRETARY, WHO
WAS DISABLED BY GUNFIRE WHEN
HINCKLEY RIDE TO KILL PRESIDENT
REAGAN.
THAT TOOK SEVEN YEARS TO PASS.
WE HAD AN ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN
THAT PASSED AT ABOUT THAT TIME,
HAD A TEN-YEAR LIFE AS A STATUTE
AND NOT A CONSENSUS TO
REAUTHORIZE IT.
THAT'S WHY I THINK WHAT THE
PRESIDENT SAID LAST NIGHT IS SO
IMPORTANT BECAUSE I THINK HE WAS
SAYING HE WANTS -- HE'S
COMMITTED TO DOING SOMETHING
ABOUT VIOLENCE IN OUR SOCIETY
AND IN THIS SECOND TERM.
IT IS WHY I'M PROPOSING A
COMMISSION TO MAKE -- ONCE YOU
APPOINTED COMMISSION, THEY HOLD
HEARINGS.
THEY TALK TO PEOPLE.
EVENTUALLY THEY PRODUCE A REPORT
WITH RECOMMENDATIONS.
THAT'S SOME SMALL GUARANTEE WE
WON'T WALK AWAY FROM THIS.
>> I THINK WHEN PEOPLE LISTEN TO
THAT AND SAY THAT'S GREAT, YOU
WANT TO POINT A COMMISSION AND
WE WILL TALK ABOUT THESE THINGS.
OFTENTIMES, NOTHING COMES OF IT.
I WANT TO ASK YOU ABOUT THE NRA
BECAUSE THE NRA REMAINED SILENT
ON THIS ISSUE.
WE HAVEN'T HEARD WORD ONE.
FACEBOOK PAGE IS DOWN.
WHY DO YOU THINK THAT IS?
WHY ISN'T THE NRA COMING OUT AND
STANDING UP FOR ITSELF WHEN SO
MANY OUT THERE ARE BLAMING THE
NRA FOR WHAT HAPPENED IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT?
>> YEAH.
WELL, I MEAN, OBVIOUSLY YOU
WOULD HAVE TO ASK FOLKS FROM THE
NRA.
LET'S JUST HOPE IT IS OUT OF
RESPECT FOR THIS TRAGEDY.
BUT, YOU KNOW, FROM THE
PRESIDENT ON DOWN, WE ALL HAVE
TO ENGAGE THE NRA AND PEOPLE WE
KNOW WHO HAVE GUNS AND WANT TO
KEEP THEIR GUNS AND REMIND THEM
JUST AS DON LEMON SAID A MOMENT
AGO, NONE OF THESE PROPOSALS
WILL TAKE GUNS OUT OF THE HANDS
OF PEOPLE WHO HAVE THEM NOW.
THIS IS ALL ABOUT TRYING TO
LIMIT ACCESS TO GUNS BY PEOPLE
WHO SHOULDN'T HAVE THEM.
BASED ON THEIR RECORDS.
AND TO KEEP MILITARY WEAPONS OFF
OF THE COMMERCIAL MARKET.
THAT SHOULDN'T INHIBIT ANYBODY'S
RIGHT TO HUNT, TARGET SHOOT, OR
EVEN TO DEFEND THEMSELVES WITH A
GUN.
I THINK -- THIS MURDER OF 20
PURE, INNOCENT CHILDREN IS A
TIPPING POINT.
I'M PROPOSING THIS COMMISSION SO
WE DON'T LOSE THE ANGER AND HURT
WE HAVE NOW BEFORE WE REALLY GET
SOMETHING DONE ABOUT THIS.
I DON'T WANT THE COMMISSION TO
BE AN EXCUSE FOR NOT DOING
SOMETHING.
IF THE PRESIDENT CAN DO
SOMETHING NOW EXECUTIVE ORDER,
GOD BLESS HIM.
IF CONGRESS CAN GET TOGETHER
SOON AND GET SOMETHING DONE, GOD
BLESS CONGRESS.
BUT --
>> EVEN AFTER GABRIELLE
GIFFORDS, ONE OF YOUR OWN, WHO
IS STILL DAMAGED TO THIS DAY
BECAUSE SOMEBODY GOT AHOLD OF A
GUN WHO SHOULDN'T HAVE, NOTHING
HAPPENED EVEN AFTER THAT.
>> YOU ARE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
I MEAN, I GO BACK TO COLUMBINE
IN 1999.
I ACTUALLY PROPOSED AFTER THAT A
COMMISSION VERY SIMILAR TO THIS.
JOHN McCAIN AND I AND OTHERS
DID.
GOT ADOPT MEDICAL THE SENATE AND
WAS DROPPED IN A CONFERENCE
COMMITTEE.
NEVER EVEN CONVENED.
BUT WE HAVE -- ALL GOT TO BE
ANGRY.
THIS IS NOT US AND THEM.
US AGAINST THE NRA OR US AGAINST
THE ENTERTAINMENT INDUSTRY.
THIS IS ALL OF US.
THIS IS A QUESTION OF HOW WE ALL
PROTECT OURSELVES FROM WANTON
VIOLENCE AND MOST FUNDAMENTALLY
HOW WE PROTECT OUR CHILDREN.
AGAIN, I WANT TO SAY -- I WAS
HEARTENED BY THE PRESIDENT'S
WORDS LAST NIGHT.
THEY WERE STRONG AND HE WAS
MOVED.
I HAPPENED TO BE AT A BILL
SIGNING AT THE WHITE HOUSE
FRIDAY MORNING WHEN HE FIRST
LEARNED ABOUT HOW EXTENSIVE THE
SLAUGHTER WAS IN NEWTOWN.
HE WAS SO VISIBLY MOVED.
I THINK HE'S -- HE'S STRUGGLED
WITH THIS OVER THE WEEKEND.
I THINK THIS IS GOING TO BE A
CENTERPIECE OF HIS SECOND TERM.
WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT IT, 12,000
PEOPLE KILLED IN THIS COUNTRY
EVERY YEAR WITH ILLEGAL GUNS,
WOW.
IF WE CAN DO SOMETHING ABOUT
THAT TO REDUCE THAT NUMBER, THAT
WILL BE A REMEMBER LEGACY FOR
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND ANYBODY WHO
SUPPORTS THESE EFFORTS.
>> SENATOR LIEBERMAN, THANK YOU
SO MUCH FOR JOINING US THIS
MORNING.
>> THANK YOU, CAROL.
>> HOW DO WE TALK ABOUT THIS
TRAGEDY?
DON LEMON WILL JOIN US AGAIN
FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
HI, DON.
>> Reporter: THANK YOU, CAROL.
ONE OF THE MOST DIFFICULT THINGS
MOVING FORWARD IN THIS TRAGEDY
IS HOW TO EXPLAIN WHAT HAPPENED
TO CHILDREN.
CHIEF MEDICAL CORRESPONDENT DR.
SANJAY GUPTA JOINS US.
YOU ARE A FATHER.
I'M AN UNCLE, GREAT UNCLE.
I CAN'T EVEN -- I HAVE BEEN ON
THE VERGE OF TEARS ALMOST EVERY
MINUTE HERE.
AS A PEAR, I HEARD YOU
EXPLAINING HOW YOU TALKED TO
YOUR GIRLS ABOUT THIS BECAUSE
THEY ARE ASKING.
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN THIS TO YOUR
KIDS?
>> YEAH.
I WAS SKYPING.
I WAS HERE WITH YOU.
YOU KNOW.
AND -- YOU KNOW, ONE OF THE
FIRST QUESTIONS, JUST INSIDE MY
7IER OLD ASKED, SHE IMMEDIATELY
ASKED FOR THE NAMES.
NAMES OF THE CHILDREN.
I THOUGHT THAT WAS INTERESTING
BECAUSE WE TALK ABOUT HUMANIZING
AND KIDS, THEY JUST DO THAT
INSTINCTIVELY.
WE OBVIOUSLY ARE TRYING TO PUT
THE
THESE THINGS IN CONTEXT FOR
PEOPLE.
THESE ARE TOUGH CONVERSATIONS.
PEOPLE TALK ABOUT THE LOSS OF
INNOCENCE.
YOU HAVE TO BE HONEST.
IN MEDICINE WE SAY YOU CHECK
YOUR OWN PULSE BEFORE GOING IN
TO TREAT A PATIENT SOMETIMES.
HERE CHECK YOUR OWN FEELINGS TO
SOME EXTENT.
YOU DON'T WANT TO OVERTALK TO
THE CHILD AND FRIGHTEN THEM MORE
THAN NECESSARY.
UP WANT TO BE HONEST.
QUESTION WILL COME UP.
MY 5-YEAR-OLD WILL ASK TODAY
BECAUSE THEY ARE GOING TO HEAR
ABOUT IT.
SOCIAL MEDIA ASK OTHERWISE AND
SAY IS THEIR SCHOOL SAFE.
YOU KNOW, YOU HAVE -- IT DIDN'T
HAPPEN IN DADDY'S SCHOOL, IT
DIDN'T HAPPEN IN MOMMY'S SCHOOL.
THIS OBVIOUSLY HAPPENED.
>> Reporter: IS YOUR WIFE
LIMITING WATCHING TELEVISION AT
HOME?
>> SHE IS.
THE TYPES OF STORIES I COVER SHE
DOES THAT OFTEN.
I THINK THIS ONE IN PARTICULAR.
>> Reporter: I THINK WHAT
PEOPLE -- YOU KNOW, WHAT --
OBVIOUSLY THE DEATH OF CHILDREN.
BUT IT IS A TIME OF THE YEAR AS
WELL.
THESE ARE KIDS WHO IN A WEEK WHO
BELIEVE IN SANTA CLAUS, WHO ARE
GOING TO BE -- BOLTING DOWN THE
STAIRS TOWARDS THAT CHRISTMAS
TREE GOING LOOK AT WHAT SANTA
BROUGHT ME.
NOW INSTEAD THE PARENTS ARE NOT
GOING -- DID I GET MY KID THE
RIGHT PRESENT?
DID I GO TOO FAR, TOO MUCH?
DID I NOT GO ENOUGH.
INSTEAD THESE PARENTS ARE
PICKING OUT COFFINS.
THAT'S WHAT I THOUGHT ABOUT THIS
MORNING WHEN I WOKE UP.
BROTHERS AND SISTERS ARE NOT
FIGURING OUT WHAT AM I GOING TO
GET LITTLE JANE.
HOW AM I GOING TO GO TO THIS
FUNERAL FOR MY SISTER AND
BROTHER.
>> I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO SAY,
DON.
YOU ARE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
YOU KNOW, I THINK -- YOU KNOW, I
DON'T EVEN KNOW HOW TO RESPOND
TO THAT.
I THINK -- SOME OF THESE THINGS
ARE UNPRECEDENTED AND SO
HORRIFIC THAT CERTAINLY AS
SCIENTISTS WE WANT TO PROVIDE
ANSWERS TO THINGS AND -- YOU
KNOW, LOOK AT HOW THESE SORTS OF
THINGS HAVE BEEN HANDLED IN THE
PAST.
I KNOW AFTER OTHER SCHOOL
SHOOTINGS, THREE TO FOUR MONTHS
LATEST, THE CHILDREN HAD
POST-TRAUMATIC DISTRESS.
IT EXISTS IN CHILDREN.
WE THINK ABOUT IT IN ADULTS.
IT CAN BE -- THEY BEHAVE
DIFFERENTLY AND MAY REGRESS IN
TERMS OF BEHAVIOR, NIECES OR
NEPHEWS MAY START TO REGRESS IN
TERMS OF DEVELOPMENT.
SLEEP -- IT SOUNDS SO SIMPLE BUT
SLEEP IS SUCH AN IMPORTANT
COMPONENT.
YOU CAN PREDICT -- SUCH A
POWERFUL PREDICTOR OF HOW THEY
WILL COPE IS IF THEY ARE GETTING
SLEEP.
SOMETHING THE PARENTS CAN DO IS
CHECK IN TO MAKE SURE YOUR CHILD
IS SLEEPING WELL WITH ALL THAT'S
GOING ON.
YEAH.
I MEAN, I DON'T -- I DON'T
KNOW -- IT IS THE HOLIDAYS, AS
YOU SAY.
I'M SURE SOME OF THE PARENTS
ALREADY PURCHASED THE PRESENTS
FOR THESE CHILDREN.
AND THEY WENT HOME TO SEE THOSE
PRESENTS LYING UNDER THE TREE.
I CAN'T -- YOU KNOW, I MEAN,
LOOK -- IT IS -- I DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO SAY.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO SAY ABOUT
THAT.
YOU HUG YOUR KIDS TIGHTER, I
GUESS.
>> Reporter: AND EVERYONE.
EVERYONE YOU CARE ABOUT.
EVERYONE YOU MAY HAVE A BEEF
WITH THAT YOU STILL -- YOU TELL
THEM, I LOVE YOU, CARE ABOUT YOU
AND I'M GLAD YOU ARE IN MY LIFE.
>> THIS WAS HAPPENING YESTERDAY.
WALKING AROUND THIS TOWN, PEOPLE
WERE COMING UP TO ME.
THEY SEE A LITTLE BIT ON TV AND
FEEL LIKE THEY KNOW YOU AND JUST
GIVE YOU A HUG.
I THINK THE IDEA THAT PEOPLE --
YOU KNOW, FEEL LIKE -- LOOK, WE
ARE GOING THROUGH THIS TOGETHER.
THE WORST THING WOULD BE TO
SUFFER IN SILENCE OR ISOLATION.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO SAY.
BUT I'M HERE WITH YOU.
YOU KNOW, AS -- IT IS A REALLY
IMPORTANT THING.
HERE'S WHAT'S GOING ON IN THE
CRISIS CENTERS AS WELL.
>> Reporter: PEOPLE NEED IT.
EVERY HUG YESTERDAY I ACCEPTED
AND EMBRACED LONGER.
THANK YOU, DR. SANJAY GUPTA.
GLAD YOU ARE HERE.
WE WILL MOVE ON IN THIS TRAGEDY.
HOW DO YOU MOVE FORWARD IN
NEWTOWN AND ELSEWHERE?
WE ARE GOING TO HEAR FROM ONE OF
THE HERO TEACHERS WHO SAVED
LIVES IN THE CHAOS.
THAT'S NEXT.
I ALWAYS WAIT
UNTIL THE LAST MINUTE.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME FOR CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
♪
>>> WE HAVE BEEN BEFORE.
MASS SHOOTING FOLLOWED BY CALLS
FOR BETTER GUN CONTROL.
BUT NOTHING MUCH SEEMS TO
HAPPEN.
BUT GOOD NEWTOWN BE THE TIPPING
POINT?
>> I'M GOING TO INTRODUCE IN THE
SENATE AND THE SAME BILL WILL BE
INTRODUCED IN THE HOUSE A BILL
TO BAN ASSAULT WEAPONS.
IT WILL BAN THE SALE, TRANSFER,
THE IMPORTATION AND THE
POSSESSION, NOT RETROACTIVELY,
BUT PERSPECTIVELY AND IT WILL
BAN THE SAME FOR BIG CLIPS,
DRUMS OR STRIPS, OF MORE THAN 10
BULLETS.
SO THERE WILL BE A BILL.
>> THERE MIGHT ABBILL INTRODUCED
BUT DOES NOT MEAN THAT BILL WILL
PASS.
LET'S BRING IN DANA BASH.
I TALKED TO SENATOR LIEBERMAN
AND HE SAYS THIS IS THE TIPPING
POINT.
IN THE COMING WEEKS WE WILL SEE
SOME MOVEMENT ON GUN CONTROL.
WHAT ARE YOU HEARING?
>> YOU KNOW, THE SENTIMENT
DEFINITELY SEEMS TO BE
DIFFERENT.
I MEAN, OVER THE -- HERE'S THE
REASON WHY WE HAVEN'T SEEN
MOVEMENT ON GUN CONTROL,
SIGNIFICANT MOVEMENT ON GUN
CONTROL, FOR THE PAST DECADE.
IT IS BECAUSE DEMOCRATS WHO HAVE
BEEN THE PARTY WHO HAVE PUSHED
IT MILLION ABOUT 2000, THEY
SHIED AWAY FROM IT.
THE REASON IS BECAUSE THEY
REALLY FELT THAT THEY WERE HURT
POLITICALLY IN RED STATES AND
EVEN IN NOT SO RED STATES BY THE
BEING SO OVERTLY FOR GUN
CONTROL.
AND SO THEY PULLED BACK
POLITICALLY.
IT HAS CHANGED IN THE PAST 24 TO
48 HOURS.
THERE'S MONTH QUESTION.
MORE DEMOCRATS, NOT JUST DIANNE
FEINSTEIN WHO IS A SENATOR WHO
HAS BEEN IN OFFICE FOR DECADES
FROM A BLUE STATE, IT IS ALSO
OTHERS LIKE JOE MANCHIN.
HE HAS AN A-RATE PROSECUTING THE
NRA.
HE'S VERY MUCH PRO-GUN.
HE USED HIMSELF, SHOOTING GUNS,
AND IN POLITICAL ADS, WEST
VIRGINIA, OBVIOUSLY IS A VERY
PRO-GUN STATE.
EVEN HE SAYS IT IS TIME TO TALK
ABOUT IT.
LISTEN TO WHAT HE SAYS.
>> I JUST CAME WITH MAY FAMILY
FROM DEER HUNTING.
I NEVER HAD MORE THAN THREE
SHELLS IN A CLIP.
SOMETIMES YOU DON'T GET MORE
THAN ONE SHOT ANYWAY AT A DEER.
IT IS COMMON SENSE.
IT IS TIME TO MOVE BEYOND
RHETORIC.
WE NEED TO SIT DOWN AND HAVE A
COMMON SENSE DISCUSSION AND MOVE
IN A REASONABLE WAY.
I ASK ALL MY FRIENDS IN THE NRA.
I HAVE BEEN AN NRA MEMBER AND
ALWAYS HAVE BEEN.
WE NEED TO SIT DOWN AND MOVE
THIS DIALOGUE TO A SENSIBLE,
REASONABLE APPROACH TO FIXING.
IT IS PART OF IT, NOT ALL OF IT
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE ON THE
TABLE AND I THINK IT WILL BE.
>> HE DIDN'T EXPLICITLY SAY HE
WOULD VOTE FOR OR SUPPORT
SENATOR FEINSTEIN'S BILL SHE
WILL INTRODUCE ON DAY ONE OF THE
NEW CONGRESS WHICH WOULD BAN
ASSAULT WEAPONS.
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN EXPIRED BACK
IN WITH OUR.
NOBODY DID ANYTHING TO REINSTATE
IT.
HE DID SAY THAT AS A HUNTER, HE
SAID, YOU DON'T NEED 30 ROUNDS
TO KILL A DEER.
THAT'S SOMETHING THAT WE MIGHT
HEAR FROM MORE AND MORE -- EVEN
DEMOCRATS WHO PREVIOUSLY HAD
BEEN AGAINST MY GUN CONTROL.
>> WE WILL SEE WHAT HAPPENS.
DANA BASH REPORTING LIVE FROM
CAPITOL HILL THIS MORNING.
>>> LET'S HEAD BACK TO NEWTOWN.
HI, DON.
>> Reporter: FAMILIES ARE
CALLING THE TEACHERS AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HEROES.
ANDERSON COOPER SPOKE TO ONE OF
THOSE TEACHERS.
JANET BALMER.
ABOUT WHAT IT WAS LIKE INSIDE OF
HER CLASSROOM.
>> Reporter: EXPLAIN AGAIN, YOU
KNEW SOMETHING WAS GOING WRONG.
HOW?
>> WELL, I MEAN, WE WERE IN OUR
CLASSROOM AND WE HEARD WHAT
SOUNDED LIKE GUNSHOTS, NOISES.
>> Reporter: YOU HEARD THAT
ON --
>> THERE WAS A LOUDSPEAKER
THAT --
>> Reporter: P.A. SYSTEM.
>> P.A. SYSTEM WAS NOT WORKING
IN THE WAY IT NORMALLY IS
BECAUSE YOU DON'T USUALLY HEAR
THINGS UNLESS SOMEONE IS MAKING
AN ANNOUNCEMENT.
THERE WERE NOISES THAT DIDN'T
SOUND CORRECT.
SO THERE WAS NO -- TELLING US IT
WAS A DRILL.
WE THOUGHT SOMETHING WAS NOT
RIGHT.
WE TOOK THE CHILDREN AND WENT
INTO A LOCKDOWN.
WE GO TO A CERTAIN PLACE IN THE
ROOM.
WE PULLED THE BLINDS DOWN.
WE LOCKED THE CLASSROOM DOORS.
AND WE COVER THE WINDOW AT THE
DOOR.
>> Reporter: THIS IS SOMETHING
YOU PRACTICED.
>> ABOUT A MONTH OR SO BEFORE.
MAKE SURE WE DO THAT, YOU KNOW,
WE -- GO TO A SAFE PLACE.
AND TYPICALLY WHEN IT IS A DRILL
THEY TELL US, OKAY, THEN WE EVEN
EXIT THE BUILDING, FOOLING
CERTAIN PATH.
AND IF THERE WAS AN EMERGENCY WE
GO DOWN TO THE SANDY HOOK
FIREHOUSE AND GATHER THERE.
WHICH IS WHAT WE DID THAT DAY.
YOU KNOW, WE KNEW THAT.
>> Reporter: YOU SAT THE KIDS
DOWN.
>> WE SAT IN THE CUBBY AWAY FROM
THE DOOR SO NO ONE COULD SEE US,
READ THEM A STORY AND TALKED TO
THEM.
THEY KEPT SAYING WE ARE HERE FOR
HOW LONG.
IT WILL BE ALWAYS LONGER.
YOU KNOW.
WHEN THEY ARE 5 YOU TELL THEM
WHATEVER YOU DO TO GET -- KEEP
THEY WILL SAFE AND CALM.
>> Reporter: THIS IS WHAT I HAVE
BEEN THINKING ABOUT ALL WEEKEND,
THOUGH.
THE COURAGE FOR YOU TO BE ABLE
TO JUST SIT THERE AND READ A
STORY AND KEEP THEM CALM.
>> I THINK THE ADRENALINE KICKS
IN AND YOU DO WHAT YOU HAVE DO.
THERE WERE TWO OTHER PEOPLE IN
THE ROOM HELPING ME WITH PULLING
DOWN THE BLINDS.
I WAS FOCUSED ON THE KIDS.
JUST KEEPING THEM SAFE AND I'M
NOT ABOUT TO TELL THEM I THINK
SOMETHING IS VERY BAD OR
REMEMBER WRONG.
SO WE WAITED AND WAITED.
YOU KNOW, IT SEEMED LIKE A VERY
LONG TIME AND MAYBE IT WAS 20
MINUTES, HALF AN HOUR.
I'M NOT SURE.
THERE WERE KNOCKS AT THE DOOR.
IT WAS -- POLICE.
SOMEONE TELLING US THAT WE HAD
TO LEAVE.
DIDN'T WANT TO OPEN THE DOOR AT
FIRST BUT WE DID.
YOU KNOW, THEY SAID HAVE THE
CHILDREN WALK, HOLD HANDS, COVER
THEIR EYE IT IS THEY COULD
BECAUSE, YOU KNOW, HE DIDN'T SAY
WHY.
HE SAID HAVE THEM COVER THEIR
EYES.
AT 5, COVERING YOUR EYES AND
WALKING ISN'T SO EASY.
I JUST -- HAD THEM, YOU KNOW,
LOOK TOWARDS THE WALL AND WE
WENT DOWN THE HALL AND OUT OF
THE BUILDING.
AND, YOU KNOW, WE GOT ON THE
SIDEWALK AND I SAID BOYS AND
GIRLS, REMEMBER THE ADVENTURE WE
HAD, WE ALL WALKED TO THE
FIREHOUSE, YOU KNOW, WE ARE
GOING TO DO THAT NOW AGAIN.
>> Reporter: IN RESPONDING TO
PEOPLE CALLING HER A HERO,
VOLLMER SAID SHE DID WHAT SHE
NEEDED TO DO TO KEEP THE
CHILDREN SAFE.
WE WILL BE RIGHT BACK.
>>> ONE OF THE BIG STORIES OF
THE DAY.
THE QUESTION FOR YOU THIS
MORNING, WHAT CAN BE DONE TO
PREVENT ANOTHER NEWTOWN?
THAT IS A TOUGH QUESTION.
BECAUSE IT REQUIRES THOUGHTFUL
DISCUSSION.
SOMETHING THAT SEEMS IMPOSSIBLE
WHEN IT COMES TO GUN VIOLENCE.
AS THE PRESIDENT SAYS, WHAT
CHOICE DO WE HAVE?
THE BLAME GAME HAS ALREADY
BEGUN.
MIKE HUCKABEE, PASTOR AND FOX
NEWS HOST, SAYS OUR GODLESS
SCHOOLS ARE TO BLAME.
>> WE ASK WHY THERE IS VIOLENCE
IN OUR SCHOOLS BUT WE
SYSTEMATICALLY REMOVED GOD FROM
OUR SCHOOLS.
SHOULD WE BE SO SURPRISED
SCHOOLS WOULD BECOME A PLACE OF
CARNAGE BECAUSE WE HAVE MADE IT
A PLACE WHERE WE DON'T WANT TO
TALK ABOUT ETERNITY, LIFE, WHAT
RESPONSIBILITY MEANS.
>> CNN CONTRIBUTOR AND TEA PARTY
SUPPORTER ERIC ERICSON SAYS IN
HIS COLUMN TODAY, SINGLE PARENT
HOMES LEAD TO VIOLENCE.
MANY ARE ALSO BLAMING VIOLENT
INDIVIDUAL YES GAMES AND MOVIES.
AFTER ALL, 11, 11 VIOLENT MOVIES
ARE NOW IN THEATERS JUST ONE
WEEK BEFORE CHRISTMAS, THE DAY
WE CELEBRATE CHRIST'S BIRTH.
>> SIMPLY A CUSTOMER TRYING TO
CONDUCT A TRANSACTION.
>> LAST CHANCE, FANCY PANTS.
>> VERY WELL.
>> INCLUDING THAT ONE.
QUENTIN TARANTINO'S "DJANGO
UNCHAINED."
>> A HORRIBLE TRAGEDY, YOU KNOW.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO SAY ABOUT
IT?
IT IS HORRIBLE.
BUT, YOU KNOW, AT THE SAME TIME,
NO, I DON'T THINK IT HAS
ANYTHING TO DO WITH THAT.
BUT THIS IS GOING BACK TO SHAKES
PEIER -- SHAKESPEARE'S DAYS.
I THINK THAT'S A VERY FACILE
ARGUMENT.
>> REPUBLICAN LAWMAKERS, LOUIE
GOMER, BLAMES TOO FEW GUNS SAY
IF THE PRINCIPAL HAD A GUN SHE
COULD HAVE TAKEN OUT THE SHOOTER
AND PREVENTED THE RAMPAGE.
MAYBE THERE ARE TOO MANY GUNS.
DIANNE FEINSTEIN PLANS TO
INTRODUCE LEGISLATION BANNING
ASSAULT WEAPONS.
BUT WILL THAT OR ANYTHING ELSE
STOP THE CARNAGE?
TALK BACK QUESTION FOR YOU
TODAY.
WHAT CAN BE DONE TO PREVENT
ANOTHER NEWTOWN?
FACEBOOK.COM/CAROLCNN.
YOUR RESPONSES, LATER THIS HOUR.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
When I'm trading,
I'm so into it,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
hours can go by before
I realize
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
that I haven't even
looked away from my screen.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
That kind of focus...
that's what I have
when I trade.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
And the StreetSmart Edge trading
platform from Charles Schwab...
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
...helps me keep an eye on
what's really important to me.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
It's packed with tools that
help me work my strategies,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
spot patterns and find
opportunities more easily.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Then, when I'm ready...
act decisively.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
I can even access it from the
cloud and trade on any computer.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
With the exact same tools,
the exact same way.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
And the reality is,
with Schwab Mobile,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
I can focus on trading
anyplace, anytime...
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
...until I choose to focus
on something else.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Trade at Schwab for
$8.95 a trade.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Open an account and trade
up to 6 months commission-free
online equity trading
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
with a $50,000 deposit.
Call 1-800-786-7803
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
and a Trading Specialist
will help you get started today.
FIVE DAYS LATER,
I HAD A MASSIVE HEART ATTACK.
BAYER ASPIRIN WAS THE FIRST
THING THE EMTS GAVE ME.
NOW, I'M ON
A BAYER ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Male Announcer ] BE SURE
TO TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE YOU BEGIN
AN ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Woman ]
LEARN FROM MY STORY.
BEFORE YOU BEGIN
AN ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
BOPRODUCTIVITY UP, COSTS DOWN,
THTIME TO MARKET REDUCED...
THOSE ARE GOOD THINGS.
UPSTAIRS, THEY WILL SEE FANTASY.
NOT FANTASY... LOGISTICS.
UPS CAME IN, ANALYZED OUR SUPPLY
CHAIN, INVENTORY SYSTEMS...
UPS?
UPS.
NOT FANTASY?
WHO WOULD HAVE THOUGHT?
I DID.
WE DID, BOB. WE DID.
GOT IT.
>>> WE ARE ALL LOOKING FOR
ANSWERS AFTER MUST HAVE TOWN.
SOME PEOPLE BELIEVE TRAGEDIES
LIKE SANDY HOOK ARING A DIRECT
RESULT OF REMOVING GOD FROM OUR
SOCIETY.
FORMER ARKANSAS GOVERNOR MIKE
HUCKABEE SAID AS MUCH.
>> WE ASK WHY THERE'S VIOLENCE
IN OUR SCHOOLS.
BUT WE HAVE SYSTEMATICALLY
REMOVED GOD FROM OUR SCHOOLS.
SHOULD WE BE SO SURPRISED
SCHOOLS WOULD BECOME PLACE OF
CARNAGE BECAUSE WE HAVE MADE
EIGHT PLACE WE DON'T WANT TO
TALK ABOUT ETERNITY, LIFE, WHAT
RESPONSIBILITY MEANS.
>> LET'S TALK ABOUT THAT WITH
FATHER THOMAS REESE.
THANK YOU, FATHER, IMPORTANT
BEING WITH US TODAY.
>> THANK YOU.
>> I'M GOING TO ASK YOU THE BIG
QUESTION FIRST.
WHY DOES GOD ALLOW THESE THINGS
TO HAPPEN?
>> WELL, THAT'S -- IF I KNEW,
COULD ANSWER THAT IN A SIMPLE
SOUND BITE, I WOULD BE A GENIUS.
THIS IS AN ISSUE THAT PEOPLE
HAVE BEEN STRUGGLING WITH FOR
CENTURIES.
ALL RELIGIOUS BELIEVERS STRUGGLE
WITH THIS QUESTION.
I THINK PART OF IT IS WHAT WE
THINK ABOUT GOD.
DO WE SEE GOD AS THIS ABSTRACT
BEING THAT IS IN CONTROL, MICRO
MANAGE IT IS UNIVERSE?
I MEAN, THE GOD OF GREEK FILLS
ON PERFECTS?
OR DO WE LOOK AT THE GOD THAT'S
PORTRAYED IN SCRIPTURES WHERE WE
SEE A GOD OF COMPASSION.
A GOD THAT, YOU KNOW, SOMETIMES
DOESN'T GET WHAT HE WANTS.
BAD THINGS HAPPEN AND HE --
WEEPS OVER IT.
HE WEEPS OVER WHAT HAPPENS TO
HIS CHILDREN.
THIS IS THE GOD FOR ME.
THE GOD THAT JESUS SHOWED US.
A GOD WHO IS SUFFERING, A GOD
WHO IS COMPASSIONATE TOWARDS HIS
FRIENDS, WHO WEPT WHEN LAZARETH
DIED.
HE DOESN'T ALWAYS GET HIS WAY
AND THAT'S WHEN THESE KIND OF
TRAGEDIES HAPPEN.
>> LET'S GO BACK TO WHAT
GOVERNOR HUCKABEE SAID.
HE SAID RAE MOVING GOD FROM OUR
PUBLIC SCHOOLS AND SOCIETY IN
GENERAL, THAT'S TO BLAME FOR THE
EVIL THAT HAPPENS IN THIS WORLD.
DO YOU AGREE?
>> WELL -- AS A CATHOLIC PRIEST,
I OBVIOUSLY BELIEVE IN THE
IMPORTANCE OF HAVING RELIGION
AND GOD IN SCHOOLS.
THAT'S WHY WE HAVE CATHOLIC
SCHOOLS.
BUT TO THINK THAT SOMEHOW
MAGICALLY THAT WILL SOLVE THE
PROBLEMS OF VIOLENCE AND
BULLYING OR WILL SOMEHOW CURE
PEOPLE WHO HAVE MENTAL DISEASES
AND DISORDERS OR WILL SOMEHOW
DEAL, YOU KNOW, TAKE CARE OF
DYSFUNCTIONAL FAMILIES, MINE,
THAT'S TOTALLY ABSURD.
AND IT ALSO MISSES THE POINT
THAT, YOU KNOW, HOW DO WE TALK
ABOUT GOD AND RELIGION IN PUBLIC
SCHOOLS IN A PLURALISTIC SOCIETY
WHERE THERE'S LOTS OF
DISAGREEMENT?
IT IS INTERESTG, ALMOST 50
YEARS AGO, 1963, WHEN THE
SUPREME COURT SAID THAT PUBLIC
SCHOOLS SHOULD NOT PROMOTE
DEVOTION, SHOULD NOT BE HAVING
PRAYERS, IT SAID WE SHOULD TEACH
ABOUT RELIGION.
WE HAVE BEEN, YOU KNOW, HAD LOTS
OF CONVERSATIONS AMONG RELIGIOUS
LEADERS ABOUT HOW TO DO THAT AND
HOW TO DO THAT IN A
CONSTITUTIONAL WAY.
BECAUSE WE IMMEDIATE TO KNOW
MORE ABOUT RELIGION.
>> THEN, YOU KNOW, ANOTHER
QUESTION I HAVE BEEN WONDER
BEING.
WHEN PEOPLE TALK ABOUT PERSONAL
LIBERTY, THEY ALWAYS SAY GOD AND
GUNS AS IF GOD AND GUNS ARE
SYNONYMOUS, ARE EQUAL.
WHERE DOES THAT COME FROM?
>> WELL, I MEAN, I THINK -- YOU
KNOW, WE HAVE LIBERTY BUT WE
ALSO HAVE RESPONSIBILITY.
WITH FREEDOM COMES
RESPONSIBILITY.
AND AS -- AS A NATION, I MEAN, I
PERSONALLY THINK, YOU KNOW, WERE
DO WE IMMEDIATE ASSAULT RIFLES?
WE DON'T IMMEDIATE THEM TO SHOOT
DEER.
WE DON'T IMMEDIATE THESE WEAPONS
THAT ARE WEAPONS FROM WAR AS
SPORTS WEAPONS.
I THINK WE SHOULD DEAL WITH THIS
IN A RATIONAL WAY.
AND, YOU KNOW, BUT IT -- IT IS
ALL OF THESE THINGS.
IT IS DEALING WITH MENTAL
DISORDERS.
IT IS DEALING WITH THE AMOUNT OF
WEAPONS THAT ARE OUT WILL IN
SOCIETY.
IT IS DEALING WITH DYSFUNCTIONAL
FAMILIES.
ALL OF THESE KINDS OF THINGS
NEED TO BE, YOU KNOW, PART OF
THE SOLUTION.
BUT, YOU KNOW, AGAIN, YOU KNOW,
FOR THE FREEDOM WE HAVE IS ALSO
THE FREEDOM TO REJECT GOD AND TO
SIN AND TO DO VIOLENT ACTS AND
THAT'S PART OF THE HUMAN
CONDITION ALSO.
>> PEAR THOMAS, THANK YOU SO
MUCH IMPORTANT BEING WITH US
THIS MORNING.
I CAN TALK TO YOU ALL DAY.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
WE WILL BE RIGHT BACK.
QUESTIONS?
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
PROGRESSIVE DIRECT AND OTHER
CAR INSURANCE COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
CALL OR CLICK TODAY.
♪
>>> A TOWN AND A NATION IN
MOURNING.
BUT AT THE SAME TIME, A PEW
FAMILIES HERE IN NEWTOWN ARE
OVERWHELMED WITH GRIEF AND
GRATITUDE.
THIS COUPLE HAD WOULD CHILDREN
INSIDE OF THE SCHOOL AND THEY
BOTH MADE IT OUT ALIVE.
THEY SAY THEIR SON RAN PAST THE
SHOOTER AND ESCAPED.
NOW THE COUPLE IS GRAPPLING WITH
THE CHALLENGE OF TELLING HIM HIS
TEACHER IS GONE.
>> HE'S REASSURING HIMSELF SHE
IS GOING TO BE OKAY.
HE REALLY, REALLY, REALLY CARED
ABOUT HIS TEACHER.
HE WAS VERY CLOSE WITH HER.
SHE REALLY LOVED THEM.
HE KEEPS SAYING I REALLY HOPE
SHE'S OKAY.
I HOPE IT IS NOT HER.
HE MISSOURI THAT SHE'S BEEN HURT
BUT DOESN'T KNOW THE END RESULT.
HE MISSOURI THE KIDS THAT HE SAW
GETTING SHOT, HE DOESN'T KNOW
THE OUTCOME.
SO I THINK HE'S REASSURING
HIMSELF IN HIS 6-YEAR-OLD MIND,
I KNOW HE IS PROCESSING IT,
BUT -- I THINK HE IS REASSURING
HIMSELF.
TELLING HIMSELF IT IS GOING TO
BE OKAY.
>> AADEN'S TEACHER WAS VICTORIA
SOTO WHO PLACED HERSELF IN FRONT
OF HER STUDENTS BEFORE THE
GUNMAN SHOT HER.
27 YEARS OLD.
HOW DO YOU TALK TO ANY CHILD WHO
HAS BEEN TRAUMATIZED?
HOW DO YOU TALK TO THEM?
LET'S ASK PSYCHOLOGIST WENDY
WALSH.
SHE JOINS US FROM LOS ANGELES.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
>> HI, DON.
>> Reporter: WHERE DO YOU BEGIN?
>> WELL, YOU BEGIN, OF COURSE,
BY DOING THE -- OBVIOUS PHYSICAL
THINGS, KEEP THEM SAFE IN THEIR
SURROUNDINGS, AS SAFE AND NORMAL
AS POSSIBLE.
LETTING THEM HAVE FREE PLAY.
LETTING THEM PLAY IN A FAMILIAR
SURROUNDINGS AND IN THEIR HOME
AND WITH THEIR REGULAR TOYS.
AND YOU LET THEM LEAD.
NOW, REMEMBER, KIDS AREN'T
VERBAL.
THEY ARE NOT GOING TO SUDDENLY
TURN DID AND GO TO MOM, I HAVE
FEARS AT NIGHT AND ANXIETY AT
NIGHT.
YOU WILL WATCH HOW THEY PLAY
WITH THEIR TOYS AND WATCH HOW
THEY DO ARTWORK.
REMEMBER, CHILDREN ARE LESS
VERBAL THAN ADULTS WHEN
EXPRESSING THINGS AND HAVE YOU
TO GIVE THEM ALL OF THE TOOLS
POSSIBLE.
AND IT HAS TO BE ABOUT GENTLE
REASSURANCE AND THE MOST
IMPORTANT PIECE IS THAT PARENTS
HAVE TO CONTAIN THEMSELVES, DON,
BECAUSE IF WE ARE -- YOU KNOW,
SOBBING IN A POOL OF TEARS,
THAT'S THE CUE TO THEM THEY
SHOULD BE FEELING MORE
DISTRESSED THAN THEY ARE.
IT IS REALLY IMPORTANT PARENTS
CONTAIN THEMSELVES.
>> Reporter: HOW DOES A PARENT
DASHES PERSON THERE PARENTS HERE
SAY -- IF A KID SAYS MOMMY, IS
BOBBY GOING TO COME BACK?
OR WHAT DO I DO WITH JANE'S
CHRISTMAS PRESENT?
I WENT AND BOUGHT IT AND SHE'S
NOT HERE.
HOW DO YOU -- WHAT DO YOU DO IN
THAT PARTICULAR SITUATION?
>> EVERY FAMILY IS DIFFERENT IN
HOW THEY EXPLAIN DEATH TO A
CHILD.
DEPENDING ON THE AGE OF THE
CHILD, IT MAY ONLY HAVE A SLIGHT
ABILITY TO UNDERSTAND REALLY
WHAT DEATH IS AND WHAT PERMT IS.
PARENTS HAVE TO THINK, THESE
ARE -- THESE ARE THE REALLY
PRICKLY TIMES OF PARENTHOOD
WHERE YOU HAVE TO EXPLAIN DEATH
TO YOUR CHILD.
DEATH OF SOMEONE IS WHO VERY
CLOSE, MAYBE EVEN A FAMILY
MEMBER, CAN BE VERY, VERY
DIFFICULT.
DON, AS YOU KNOW, I TWO
DAUGHTERS MYSELF.
I HAD TO EXPLAIN THIS TO THEM.
I'M -- I'M FOLLOWING THE LARGE
GROUP ON TWITTER THAT ARE DOING
20 ACTS OF KINDNESS AS A FAMILY,
AS A WAY TO HONOR THE SPIRITS OF
EACH OF THE 20 CHILDREN WHO
DIED.
THEREFORE, YESTERDAY WE BOUGHT
SOME THINGS FOR FOSTER CHILDREN
FOR CHRISTMAS.
WE MADE A TOILETRY KIT FOR A
HOMELESS MAN.
WE DID A -- FOOD DRIVE AND
DONATE TO A FOOD BANK.
WE HAVE THREE DOWN AND 17 MORE
TO GO.
THIS IS A WAY TO ALLOW MY
CHILDREN TO GRIEVE AND TO TAKE
POSITIVE STEPS AT THE SAME TIME
TOWARD HEALING.
>> Reporter: YEAH.
I HAVE TO SAY, YOU KNOW, THESE
ARE REMARKABLE PARENTS, WENDY,
BUT IT WOULD BE HARD TO BE -- I
WOULD IMAGINE A GOOD PARENT AND
TAKE CARE OF YOUR CHILD WHEN YOU
ARE TRYING TO TAKE CARE OF
YOURSELF, NO PARENT WANTS TO
LOSE A CHILD.
HOW -- HOW DO YOU BALANCE THAT
AS A PARENT?
>> LOOK, RIGHT NOW MOST OF THOSE
PARENTS ARE STILL IN COMPLETE
SHOCK, DON.
THIS TRAUMA IS GOING TO WORK ITS
WAY THROUGH THEIR BODY AND
THROUGH THEIR BRAIN AND IN MANY
DIFFERENT WAYS.
THE THING ABOUT POST-TRAUMATIC
STRESS DISORDER, WHETHER IT IS
IN THE CHILDREN OR THE PARENT OR
ANYONE WHO WITNESSED OR PEOPLE
WATCHING IT ON TV, IT IS FOR
EVERYBODY, IT IS DIFFERENT.
SOME PEOPLE BECOME VERY ACTIVE.
THEY TAKE TO FACEBOOK AND
TWITTER AND TRY TO SOLVE
PROBLEMS.
OTHER PEOPLE GET VERY DISTRACTED
AND RYE TO AVOID THE FEELINGS
AND GET BUSY DOING A LOT OF
OTHER THINGS.
SOME OTHER PEOPLE, THE LUCKY
ARTISTS IN THE WORLD, CAN CREATE
SOME VERY PROVOCATIVE,
COMPASSIONATE ART.
WE ALL DEAL WITH TRAUMA IN
DIFFERENT WAYS.
IT IS REALLY IMPORTANT TO
REMEMBER THAT BECAUSE OF THIS,
CHILDREN'S BRAINS CAN HEAL VERY
WELL.
NOT ALL THESE CHILDREN ARE GOING
TO HAVE POST-TRAUMATIC STRESS
DISORDER.
MANY OF THEM MAY HEAL VERY WELL.
MAYBE EASIER THAN THE PARENTS
AND ADULTS.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT THE OUTCOME
IS GOING TO BE IN THE SHORT
TERM, THOUGH, WE WANT TO BE
CALM, REASSURING, AND LOVING.
>> Reporter: YOU ARE ABSOLUTELY
RIGHT.
WHEN I WAS YOUNGER, IT WAS MUCH
EASIER TO GET OVER THINGS.
NOW YOU REALIZE THAT, YOU KNOW,
LIFE IS SHORT.
IT IS TOUGHER SOMETIMES TO
REALLY GET OVER IT.
YOU REALIZE SOMEONE IS NEVER
COMING BACK AS AN ADULT.
THANK YOU, DR. WENDY, WE
APPRECIATE IT.
[ Male Announcer ]
RESEARCH SUGGESTS CELL HEALTH
PLAYS A KEY ROLE
THROUGHOUT OUR LIVES.
One A Day Men's 50+
IS A COMPLETE MULTIVITAMIN
DESIGNED FOR MEN'S HEALTH
CONCERNS AS WE AGE.
IT HAS 7 ANTIOXIDANTS
TO SUPPORT CELL HEALTH.
One A Day Men's 50+.
IT HAS 7 ANTIOXIDANTS
TO SUPPORT CELL HEALTH.
Meet the 5-passenger
Ford C-MAX Hybrid.
When you're carrying
a lot of weight,
C-MAX has a nice little trait,
You see, C-MAX helps
you load your freight,
with its foot-activated
lift gate.
But that's not
all you'll see,
Cause C-MAX also
beats Prius v,
with better MPG.
Say hi to the all-new 47
combined MPG C-MAX Hybrid.
>>> TODAY WILL NOT BE AN EASY
DAY IN THE CLASSROOM.
STUDENTS RETURN TO SCHOOL.
AS PARENTS WORRY ABOUT THEIR
SAFETY.
CA
YOU SPOKE WITH SEVERAL PARENTS
WHO WERE TAKING THEIR CHILDREN
TO SCHOOL THIS MORNING.
WHAT DID THEY TELL YOU?
>> YEAH, AT SANDRA DAY O'CONNOR
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN MESA,
ARIZONA, OUTSIDE OF PHOENIX.
THERE WAS A LOT OF CONCERN BY
PARENTS WHO ARE BRINGING THEIR
KIDS TO SCHOOL TODAY.
THE FIRST DAY OF SCHOOL AFTER
THAT TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT.
THIS IS A VERY MIDDLE-CLASS
COMMUNITY.
IT IS A COMMUNITY NOT THAT FAR
AWAY JUST A YEAR AGO FROM TUCSON
WHERE A MASS SHOOTING HAPPENED.
SIX PEOPLE KILLED.
CONGRESSWOMAN GIFFORDS INJURED.
THESE FOLKS HAVE SOME EXPERIENCE
WITH THESE MASS SHOOTINGS.
WE ASKED THEM WHAT THEIR
THOUGHTS ARE ON GUN CONTROL.
AND JUST LIKE THE REST OF
THENITION, PARENTS HERE ARE VERY
DIVIDED.
>> THERE SHOULD BE MORE GUN
CONTROL, YES.
>> Reporter: WHY DO YOU THINK
THAT?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, GUNS ARE --
GUNS ARE IN THE WRONG HANDS,
VERY DANGEROUS.
>> GUNS DON'T KILL PEOPLE.
PEOPLE KILL PEOPLE.
>> DEFINITELY SHOULD BE A GUN
CONTROL ISSUE.
SHOULD BE NO GUNS OUT THERE.
LOT OF CRAZY PEOPLE DON'T KNOW
HOW TO HANDLE GUNS.
>> I DON'T THINK TAKING GUNS OUT
OF CIVILIANS WHO ARE GOOD
CONTRIBUTING MEMBERS OF SOCIETY
ARE THE ANSWER.
>> Reporter: THAT FATHER YOU
HEARD WILL, MATTHEW, HE'S
ACTUALLY AN ASSISTANT PASTOR AT
A LOCAL CHURCH.
HE SAYS THE ANSWER, HE BELIEVES,
IS MORE PEOPLE SHOULD BE ARMED.
HERE'S SOMETHING YOU HEAR A LOT
FROM GUN ADVOCATES HERE IN
ARIZONA AND IN OTHER PLACES.
THAT IF THAT TEACHER OR SCHOOL
OFFICIALS IN CONNECTICUT WERE
ARMED, THAT MAYBE SO MANY
CHILDREN WOULD NOT HAVE BEEN
KILLED.
WE ALSO TALKED TO THE PRINCIPAL
AT THIS SCHOOL ABOUT SECURITY
MEASURES THAT HE MAY BE TAKING
IN THE WAKE OF WHAT HAPPENED ON
FRIDAY.
HE SAID NOTHING SPECIAL BUT THEY
DID GO THROUGH AND REVIEW THEIR
SECURITY PROCEDURES HERE AT THE
SCHOOL, FOUND DOORS THAT MAYBE
THAT WERE OPEN THAT SHOULD HAVE
BEEN LOCKED.
THE PARENTS WE SPOKE WITH SAID
THEY ARE NOT CONCERNED ABOUT
SECURITY HERE AT THIS SCHOOL
TODAY BUT THEY ARE VERY
CONCERNED ABOUT THE ISSUE OF GUN
CONTROL NATIONALLY.
>> YOU TALK ABOUT THE DESIRE FOR
GUNS.
I WOULD -- I WOULD THINK GUN
SHOWS ACROSS THE COUNTRY, MAYBE
THE -- CANCELED SOME OF THEM?
>> Reporter: WELL, THAT'S NOT
EXACTLY TRUE.
AS A MATTER OF FACT, MY
COLLEAGUE WAS AT A GUN SHOW IN
VENTURA, CALIFORNIA, OVER THE
WEEKEND.
AND WILL BE BRING YOU A REPORT
THAT INCLUDES SOME OF THE SNEAKS
WERE ATTENDING THAT GUN SHOW
LATER IN THE DAY ON CNN.
THEY WERE TELLING US THAT THIS
WAS ABOUT AS BUSY AS THEY HAD
EVER SEEN THAT GUN SHOW.
OBVIOUSLY SOME OF THESE GUN
ENTHUSIASTS AND PEOPLE THAT
BELIEVE IN GUN OWNERSHIP WANTING
TO GET THEIR HANDS ON MORE
WEAPONS BECAUSE THEY FEAR THAT
TIGHTER GUN CONTROL REGULATIONS
ARE COMING IN THE WAKE OF THE
SHOOTING.
[ Female Announcer ]
WHAT IF THE NEXT BIG THING,
ISN'T A THING AT ALL?
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
♪
BECOMING
PART OF THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
TREES WILL TALK TO NETWORKS
WILL TALK TO SCIENTISTS
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE.
CARS WILL TALK TO ROAD SENSORS
WILL TALK TO STOPLIGHTS
ABOUT TRAFFIC EFFICIENCY.
THE AMBULANCE WILL TALK
TO PATIENT RECORDS
WILL TALK TO DOCTORS
ABOUT SAVING LIVES.
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
THE NEXT BIG THING?
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
♪
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
♪
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
♪
>>> LOT OF YOU WATCHED FOOTBALL
THIS SUNDAY WHILE THE NFL MARKED
THE DEATHS OF THE SANDY HOOK
VICTIMS WITH A MOMENT OF SILENCE
BEFORE EACH GAME.
THIS IS FROM GREEN BAY, CHICAGO.
>> AT THIS TIME PLEASE STAND AND
JOIN IN A MOMENT OF SILENT
REFLECTION FOR THE VICTIM, THEIR
FAMI
FAMILIES, AND LOVED ONES.
>> BUT THERE WERE OTHER MUCH
MORE TOUCHING TRIBUTES.
VICTOR CRUZ, MINE, JUST --
BREAKS YOUR HEART.
>> I KNOW.
IT IS A HEARTBREAKING STORY.
YOU KNOW, COUPLE OF TEAMS IN
CLOSE PROXIMITY TO NEWTOWN,
GIANTS PATRIOTS OFFERING
TRIBUTES AS WELL.
I WANT TO START WITH A POIGNANT
MOMENT, THOUGH, THAT TOOK PLACE
IN ST. LOUIS.
THIS WAS PRIOR TO THE
VIKINGS/RAMS GAME.
YOU SEE THE PLAYERS IN APRIL
GIANT CIRCLE INSIDE OF THE
CIRCLE, TWO HEAD COACHES AND TWO
NUMBER 26ES FROM BOTH TEAMS
HOLDING HANDS IN PRAYER.
REPRESENTING THE NUMBER OF
SCHOOL VICTIMS.
SUNDAY NATURE AT GILLETTE
STADIUM, FOXBOROUGH,
MASSACHUSETTS, IT IS THE
PATRIOTS, NEW ENGLAND'S ONLY NFL
TEAM, PAYING TRIBUTE BY LIGHTING
26 WHITE FLARES.
WES WELKER'S HELMET.
NEWTOWN IS 60 MILES NORTH OF NEW
YORK CITY.
THIS IS THE STORY YOU ARE
TALKING ABOUT.
IT INVOLVES THE GIANTS.
THEY WORE THE LETTERS SHES.
THE MOST PERSONAL TRIBUTE,
INVOLVED VICTOR CRUZ.
THE FAVORITE PLAYER OF ONE OF
THE MURDERED CHILDREN.
6-YEAR-OLD JACK PINTO.
CRUZ HAS BEEN IN CONTACT WITH
THE PINTO FAMILY AND HE SPOKE
FOLLOWING THE GAME ALONG WITH
HIS HEAD COACH.
LET'S LISTEN.
>> SEEM LIKE A STRONG FAMILY.
I SPOKE TO -- SPOKE TO THE OLDER
BROTHER AND, YOU KNOW, HE WAS
DISTRAUGHT AS WELL.
I TOLD THEM TO STAY STRONG AND I
WILL DO WHATEVER I CAN TO HONOR
HIM.
>> WE FELT TERRIBLY ABOUT IT.
I'M SURE THE WHOLE NATION DOES.
IT IS NOT JUST US.
BUT BEING CLOSE TO HOME, IT
DID -- THE PLAYERS WERE GREATLY
UPSET ABOUT IT.
AND -- MANY OF THE PLAYERS HAVE
RUNG CHILDREN.
THEY CAN EMPATHIZE PARENTS OF
THE YOUNG CHILDREN KILLED.
>> JACK PINTO'S FUNERAL IS THIS
AFTERNOON.
AND ACCORDING TO VICTOR CRUZ,
THE FAMILY IS CONSIDERING
BURYING THE CHILD IN CRUZ'S
JERSEY.
>> WILL VICTOR CRUZ GO TO THE
FUNERAL?
>> THAT'S -- THAT WAS THE PLAN.
I WOULD IMAGINE IF POSSIBLE HE
IS GOING TO ATTEND.
>> JUST REALLY HEARTBREAKING.
IT REALLY IS.
WE ARE ALL TRYING DEAL WITH IT
IN OUR OWN WAY.
VICTOR CRUZ TRYING TO DEAL WITH
TONIGHT HIS WAY.
GIVE SOME COMFORT TO THE FAMILY.
>> RIGHT.
YOU KNOW, ATHLETES GRIEVE LIKE
EVERYONE ELSE.
THIS IS THEIR EXPRESSION OF THAT
GRIEF OVER THE WEEKEND.
>> THANKS SO MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> WE WILL BE RIGHT BACK.
WE UNDERSTAND.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
>>> TALK BACK QUESTION TODAY A
TOUGH ONE.
WHAT CAN BE DONE TO PREVENT
ANOTHER NEWTOWN?
WE IMMEDIATE A BAN ON ASSAULT
WEAPONS AND MORE RESTRICTED
HANDGUN USE.
MONTH SELF-RESPECTING HUNTER
WORTH HIS SALT NEEDS AN
AK-47-TYPE WEAPON.
WE NEED TO HAVE A PHYSIOLOGICAL
TEST FOR EVERYONE THAT BUY AS
GUN.
PEOPLE ARE UNSTABLE AND HAVE
MENTAL ILLNESS SHOULD BE BANNED
FROM GETTING GUNS.
I THINK HE MEANT PSYCHOLOGICAL.
MAYBE WE SHOULD BE TALKING ABOUT
ALL THE VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES OUR
CHILDREN ARE WATCHING.
THEY START SHOOTING PEOPLE WITH
THE GAME.
WHEN THEY PLAY THE GAMES THEY
BECOME NUMB TO THE VALUE OF REAL
LIFE.
WE IMMEDIATE BETTER SECURITY ANY
LOCATION WHERE WE LIVE OUR
CHILDREN.
KEEP THE CLASSROOMS SEPARATED
FROM THE ADMINISTRATION.
MAYBE BY SECONDARY SECURITY
DOORS, SWIPE CARDS TO OPEN,
ENTER AND EXIT.
THIS FROM NANCY.
NO ASSAULT RIFLES WHEN THE
CONSTITUTION WAS WRITTEN AND I
CAN'T BELIEVE THE WRITERS
INTENDED THE RIGHT TO BEAR GUNS
THAT CAN MOW DOWN HUNDREDS OF
PEOPLE DOWN AT A TIME.
MANY STATES CUT THEIR FUNDING OF
STATE MENTAL INSTITUTIONS,
SOCIETY HAS TO REAP THE
REPERCUSSIONS FOR THAT.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR JOINING
THE CONVERSATION.
MORE THAN A THOUSAND OF YOU