>> NOW WE'RE GETTING THERE.
>> BUT I WAS SUCH A NICE JEWISH
GIRL, THAT I SAID, MARLON, I
CAN'T STAY OVERFLIGHT WITH YOU.
I I WILL GO WITH YOU FOR THE DAY
BUT YOU HAVE TO TAKE ME HOME.
>> SO MARLON CLEARLY WANTED TO
DO MORE THAN SEE THE FLOWERS
WITH YOU.
>> HE WANTED TO SLEEP IN THE
DESERT WITH ME.
>> YOU TURNED DOWN MARLON
BRANDO?
>> YEAH, ABSOLUTELY.
>> HOW DID HE TAKE REJECTION?
>> IT WAS FINE.
>> A REMARKABLE CONVERSATION
WITH A REMARKABLE LADY.
BARBRA STREISAND WITH ME FOR THE
HOUR TOMORROW NIGHT AT 9:00 P.M.
EAST PERSON THAT'S ALL FOR
TONIGHT.
AC 360 STARTS NOW.
"AC 360" STARTS NOW.
>>> BREAKING NEWS TONIGHT.
THE WOMAN BELIEVED TO BE
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S FIRST CHOICE
FOR SECRETARY OF STATE SAYS NO
THANKS.
U.N. AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE.
SHE'S THE ONE CAUGHT UP IN THE
CONTROVERSY OVER HER STATEMENTS
FOLLOWING THE MURDER OF FOUR
AMERICANS IN LIBYA.
SHE'S THE ONE, YOU'LL RECALL,
THE PRESIDENT STOOD UP USING
SOME PRETTY BLUNT LANGUAGE,
SAYING THAT ANYONE WHO'S GOT A
PROBLEM WITH HER HAS A PROBLEM
WITH HIM.
INSTEAD, THERE WON'T BE A
CONFRONTATION BECAUSE LATE
TODAY, AMBASSADOR RICE TOOK
HERSELF OUT OF CONTENTION,
WRITING THE PRESIDENT SHE'S
HONORED TO BE CONSIDERED FOR THE
OFFICE, WRITING "I AM FULLY
CONFIDENT THAT I COULD SERVE OUR
COUNTRY ABLY AND EFFECTIVELY IN
THAT ROLE.
HOWEVER, IF NOMINATED, I AM NOW
CONVINCED THAT THE CONFIRMATION
PROCESS WOULD BE LENGTHY,
DISRUPTIVE AND COSTLY.
THAT TRADE-OFF IS SIMPLY NOT
WORTH IT FOR OUR COUNTRY."
>> I MADE THE DECISION THAT IT
WAS THE BEST THING FOR OUR
COUNTRY, FOR THE AMERICAN PEOPLE
THAT I NOT CONTINUE TO BE
CONSIDERED BY THE PRESIDENT FOR
NOMINATION AS SECRETARY OF
STATE, BECAUSE I DIDN'T WANT TO
SEE A CONFIRMATION PROCESS THAT
WAS VERY PROLONGED, VERY
POLITICIZED, VERY DISTRACTING
AND VERY DISRUPTIVE, BECAUSE
THERE ARE SO MANY THINGS WE NEED
TO GET DONE AS A COUNTRY, AND
THE FIRST SEVERAL MONTHS OF A
SECOND-TERM PRESIDENT'S AGENDA
IS REALLY THE OPPORTUNITY TO GET
THE CRUCIAL THINGS DONE.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION
REFORM, BALANCED DEFICIT
REDUCTION, JOB CREATION.
THAT'S WHAT MATTERS.
AND TO THE EXTENT THAT MY
NOMINATION COULD HAVE DELAYED OR
DISTRACTED OR DEFLECTED OR MAYBE
EVEN SOME OF THESE PRIORITIES
IMPOSSIBLE TO ACHIEVE, I DIDN'T
WANT THAT, AND I'D MUCH PREFER
TO CONTINUE DOING WHAT I'M
DOING, WHICH IS A JOB I LOVE AT
THE UNITED NATIONS.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA ACCEPTED HER
DECISION TO BOW OUT, CALLING HER
AN EXTRAORDINARILY CAPABLE,
PATRIOTIC AND PASSIONATE PUBLIC
SERVANT.
MORE WITH WHAT DECISION AND
WHO'S THE LEADING CANDIDATE,
DANA BASH, GLORIA BORGER AND
DAVID BERGEN.
WHAT WAS THE PIVOTAL MOMENT FOR
AMBASSADOR ROSE?
>> Reporter: NO QUESTION, IT WAS
THE SERIES OF MEETINGS A COUPLE
WEEKS AGO HERE ON THE HILL,
FIRST OF ALL WITH HER CHIEF
REPUBLICAN FOES, SENATORS
McCAIN, GRAHAM AND AYOTTE, BUT
MORE IMPORTANTLY IT WAS PROBABLY
WITH A REPUBLICAN WHO HADN'T
QUITE MADE UP HER MIND, THE
MODERATE REPUBLICAN FROM MAINE,
SUSAN COLLINS.
BY ALL ACCOUNTS, THAT MEETING
DID NOT GO WELL AT ALL, BECAUSE
ACCORDING TO A SOURCE FAMILIAR
WITH THAT MEETING, SHE DIDN'T
WANT TO ANSWER REALLY BASIC
QUESTIONS AND GOT FRUSTRATED AND
MAYBE EVEN A LITTLE PRICKLY AT
SOME OF THE BASIC QUESTIONS.
AND AFTER THAT, THE FEELING EVEN
AMONG SOME DEMOCRATS WHO TALKED
TO THESE REPUBLICANS WAS THEY
REALLY WEREN'T SURE IF SHE CAN'T
HANDLE MEETINGS WITH U.S.
SENATORS, HOW IS SHE GOING TO BE
ON THE WORLD STAGE REPRESENTING
THE U.S. THERE?
SO, THAT DEFINITELY WAS AN
ISSUE.
THERE'S NO QUESTION THAT THE
PRESIDENT IN HIS STATEMENT MADE
CLEAR THAT HE DIDN'T THINK SUSAN
RICE WAS TREATED FAIRLY.
THERE'S NO QUESTION THERE WAS
POLITICS AT PLAY HERE BY
REPUBLICANS WHO WERE REALLY,
REALLY ANGRY ABOUT BENGHAZI, AND
SHE ILLUSTRATED THAT, BUT IT WAS
MORE THAN THAT.
IT WAS ALSO PERSONALITY DRIVEN,
BECAUSE DEMOCRATS EVEN THINK SHE
IS VERY SMART AND CAPABLE BUT
MAYBE DOESN'T HAVE THE
PERSONALITY FOR THE JOB.
>> GLORIA, I HEARD YOU SAY
EARLIER THAT YOU THINK
AMBASSADOR RICE UNDERESTIMATED
THE CLUB.
WHAT DID YOU MEAN BY THAT?
>> RIGHT.
THAT WAS FROM A DEMOCRAT VERY
CLOSE TO THE WHITE HOUSE.
SHE SAID THE CLUB IS REALLY
IMPORTANT ON CAPITOL HILL.
JOHN KERRY IS THE LEADER IN THAT
CLUB, JOHN McCAIN LIKES HIM AN
AWFUL LOT AND WOULD CLEARLY GO
ALONG WITH THAT NOMINATION.
ALSO, WHEN SHE TRAVELED UP THERE
AND SHE WANTED TO GO UP THERE TO
TALK TO THESE SENATORS, THERE IS
A SENSE FROM THE SOURCE THAT SHE
KIND OF OVERESTIMATED HER
ABILITY TO WOO THEM OVER ON THE
QUESTION OF BENGHAZI.
THAT WAS A REALLY BIG
PRE-EXISTING CONDITION FOR HER,
AND DANA JUST POINTED OUT, SHE
DIDN'T WIN OVER SUSAN COLLINS,
WHO WAS QUITE IMPORTANT TO HER.
>> AND DAVID, I MEAN, WHAT DO
YOU MAKE OF THIS?
IS THIS JUST A SIGN OF HOW
PARTISAN THINGS HAVE BECOME, OR
WAS IT PRETTY CLEAR FROM AS SOON
AS THE CONTROVERSY OVER
BENGHAZI, THE COMMENTS BEGAN,
THAT IT WASN'T GOING TO HAPPEN?
>> I DON'T THINK THIS IS JUST
ABOUT PARTISANSHIP, AND I ALSO
DON'T THINK IT'S JUST ABOUT
BENGHAZI.
THAT WAS AN ISSUE, OF COURSE,
BUT IN THIS CASE, THERE ARE A
NUMBER OF SENATORS ON BOTH SIDES
OF THE AISLE WHO BELIEVE THAT
THE UNITED STATES HAS SOME TOUGH
WORK AHEAD IN INTERNATIONAL
RELATIONS.
YOU KNOW, SOMEONE HAS GOT TO GO
AND NEGOTIATION WITH THE
IRANIANS TO MAKE SURE WE DON'T
GET INTO A CONFLICT OVER THERE
AND SOMEONE WITH THE KIND OF
TOUGHNESS AND AUTHORITY OF A JIM
BAKER.
AND FRANKLY, THERE WAS A SENSE
ABOUT SUSAN RICE THAT, EVEN
THOUGH SHE IS VERY TALENTED AND
I THINK SHE DID A GENEROUS THING
TODAY BY WITHDRAWING, SHE REALLY
WAS LOYAL TO HER PRESIDENT BY
DOING THAT, BUT THERE WAS ALSO A
SENSE THAT SHE DIDN'T HAVE THE
WEIGHT, SHE DIDN'T HAVE THE
BACKGROUND THAT SENATOR KERRY
DOES, AND HE IS EXTREMELY
SCHOOLED AND KNOWS THE ROUGH
PARTS OF THE WORLD.
AND THERE WAS A SENSE IN THE
SENATE, YOU KNOW, THAT PEOPLE
THERE WOULD JUST BE MORE
COMFORTABLE WITH HIM
REPRESENTING THE UNITED STATES.
>> DAVID, WHAT DO YOU THINK THIS
SAYS ABOUT PRESIDENT OBAMA
HIMSELF, BECAUSE IT CERTAINLY
SEEMED LIKE, ESPECIALLY IN THE
LAST MONTH OR SO, THAT HE WAS
DIGGING IN HIS HEELS PREPARING
FOR A FIGHT?
>> WELL, IT DID SEEM LIKE THAT,
AND THERE WAS ALSO -- YOU KNOW,
THERE HAD BEEN VARIOUS REPORTS
THAT HE'S BEEN AGONIZING OVER
THIS CHOICE, AND IN A SENSE, SHE
LET HIM OFF.
SHE RECOGNIZES AGONY AND REMOVED
IT.
I THINK ONE CAN READ INTO THIS
THAT HE DOESN'T WANT A SERIES OF
FIGHTS WITH REPUBLICANS ACROSS
THE BOARD.
HE'S GOT A BIG FIGHT ON HIS
HANDS ON THE FISCAL CLIFF, AND
YOU KNOW, IT MAY BE ONE STRUGGLE
TOO MANY WHEN HE WANTS TO GET
HIS SECOND TERM OFF AND RUNNING
AND HE DOESN'T WANT TO BE
ENSNARED LIKE THIS.
THIS HAPPENS TO PRESIDENTS, AND
WE'VE HAD SOME REALLY GOOD
PEOPLE WHO HAVE NOT MADE IT
THROUGH THIS PROCESS.
I REMEMBER SO WELL THE ICONIC
FIGURE TED SORENSEN, WHO WAS
NOMINATED TO BE CIA CHIEF, AND
IT SORT OF JUST FELL APART AFTER
TIME, AND TED SORENSEN WENT ON
TO GREAT THINGS AND HE'LL BE
WELL REMEMBERED, BUT IT WAS A
TOUGH CHAPTER IN HIS LIFE.
>> ANDERSON, YOU WERE JUST
TALKING ABOUT THE SENATE BEING
MORE COMFORTABLE WITH JOHN
KERRY.
I THINK IN A WAY, THE PRESIDENT
WOULD HAVE BEEN A LOT MORE
COMFORTABLE WITH SUSAN RICE.
SHE'S AN OLD FRIEND OF HIS.
IT'S NOT THAT HE DOESN'T LIKE
JOHN KERRY.
JOHN KERRY HELPED HIM OUT DURING
THE DEBATES, HE'S KNOWN HIM FOR
A LONG TIME.
SUSAN RICE IS A DEAR OLD FRIEND,
AND YOU KNOW, THERE'S ANOTHER
ISSUE HERE, WHICH IS THE
QUESTION OF DIVERSITY.
BECAUSE IF IT SORT OF ALL STACKS
UP AS WE THINK IT'S GOING, IT
LOOKS LIKE THE TOP FOUR CABINET
POSTS COULD NOW POTENTIALLY BE
FILLED BY MEN, AND I'M SURE THAT
THAT'S SOMETHING THE WHITE HOUSE
REALLY IS THINKING ABOUT.
>> AND DANA, I MEAN, THIS TEAM
THAT LOOKS TO BE FALLING INTO
PLACE, HUCHUCK HAGEL TALKING ABT
REPLACING PANETTA, DOES IT SEEM
LIKE IT WILL PASS CONFIRMATION
IN THE SENATE IF JOHN KERRY IS
THE CANDIDATE?
>> IT DOES, UNLESS THERE'S
SOMETHING WE DON'T KNOW ABOUT,
LIKE IF SENATE MINORITY LEADER,
TOM DASCHLE, AN IMPORTANT MEMBER
OF THE CLUB, HE DIDN'T MAKE IT
THROUGH BECAUSE OF A SURPRISE
ISSUE WITH TAX RETURNS.
WITH JOHN KERRY, EVEN THE
REPUBLICAN LEADER LATE TODAY
SAID KIND WORDS ABOUT HIM.
IT IS VIRTUALLY SURE THAT HE IS
GOING TO GET THROUGH THE SENATE
BECAUSE HE HAS BEEN VETTED IN
MANY WAYS BECAUSE HE WAS THE
PRESIDENTIAL CANDIDATE.
YOU DON'T GET MORE VETTED THAN
THAT.
WITH REGARD TO CHUCK HAGEL, SAME
THING, HE IS SOMEBODY WHO MAYBE
DIDN'T HAVE THE CLOSEST
RELATIONSHIPS HERE, BUT THE FACT
THAT IT WOULD BE A BIPARTISAN
PICK, SINCE HE'S A REPUBLICAN,
WOULD GO A LONG WAY LIKELY.
SO, YES, IT DOES LOOK LIKE IT'S
SHAPING UP.
THE ONE THING I WOULD SAY ABOUT
SUSAN RICE, THE SORT OF VETTING
HERE ON CAPITOL HILL, IS THE
PRESIDENT IS MAYBE LOOKING AT
HER TO BE NATIONAL SECURITY
ADVISER.
SHE WOULDN'T NEED SENATE
CONFIRMATION.
>> INTERESTING.
THANK YOU.
>>> POLITICS NOW AND HIGH STAKES
WHEN IT COMES TO THE TAXES YOU
PAY, THE SIZE OF GOVERNMENT, THE
ECONOMY, THE WORKS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND JOHN BOEHNER
BACK AT IT TONIGHT TRYING ONCE
AGAIN TO REACH A DEAL ON THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
THE QUESTION IS, WILL IT BE ANY
DIFFERENT THIS TIME?
LET'S CHECK WITH JESSICA YELLIN.
>> HEY, ANDERSON.
TONIGHT THE TWO MET FOR 50
MINUTES IN THE OVAL OFFICE AS
THEY STRUGGLED TO FIND A WAY OUT
OF THIS STALEMATE, AND SO FAR,
NO WORD OF BREAKTHROUGH.
AIDES TO BOTH MEN DESCRIBE THE
CONVERSATION AS FRANK, AND WE'RE
TOLD THAT LINES OF COMMUNICATION
REMAIN OPEN.
NOW, THAT IS POLITICAL SPEAK,
AND I WILL TRANSLATE IT FOR YOU.
FRANK, THAT GENERALLY MEANS THAT
THE CONVERSATION WAS SOMEWHAT
TENSE.
LINES OF COMMUNICATION REMAINS
OPEN, THAT MEANS THAT THE TWO
MEN'S STAFF WILL CONTINUE
TALKING.
AND IN FACT, I'VE CONFIRMED THAT
THERE IS NO CURRENT PLAN FOR THE
TWO MEN, THE PRESIDENT AND
SPEAKER BOEHNER, TO HAVE A
FOLLOW-UP MEETING AS OF YET, AND
SPEAKER BOEHNER DOES PLAN TO
RETURN HOME TO OHIO TOMORROW.
NOW, THAT'S A CHALLENGE FOR A
DEAL TO COME TOGETHER BECAUSE
THEY ARE RUNNING OUT OF TIME.
THEY ARE ALL BUT OUT OF TIME TO
GET A DEAL DONE BEFORE THE
CHRISTMAS DEADLINE AND NEXT TO
OUT OF TIME TO GET ONE DONE
BEFORE THE NEW YEAR, ANDERSON.
>> JESSICA, THANKS VERY MUCH.
LET US KNOW WHAT YOU THIN
THINK, @ANDERSONCOOPER.
I'LL BE TWEETING TONIGHT.
>>> NEXT, AN OUT BREAK OF A
DEADLY DISEASE AND ALLEGATIONS
OF WHAT THE HOSPITAL SYSTEM KNEW
ABOUT THE RISK.
ñç@RÑo
>>> KEEPING THEM HONEST NOW,
LOOKING FOR FACTS TONIGHT, NOT
OFFERING OPINIONS OR PLAYING
FAVORITES.
OUR GOAL TONIGHT IS REAL
REPORTING, AS IT IS EVERY NIGHT,
FINDING TRUTH AND CALLING OUT
HYPOCRISY, BUT TONIGHT THE
STAKES ARE LIFE AND DEATH.
EVERY YEAR, MILLIONS OF
AMERICANS PUT THEIR LIFE ON THE
LINE FOR THE COUNTRY CHECK INTO
VA HOSPITALS.
ALL DESERVE THE BEST CARE
POSSIBLE.
CERTAINLY, NONE SHOULD EVER
EXPECT THAT A TRIP TO THE
HOSPITAL MIGHT MAKE THEM SICK OR
EVEN KILL THEM, YET ONE
PITTSBURGH AREA FAMILY SAYS THAT
IS EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED TO
THEIR DAD AND THEY'RE FINDING
MORE CASES LIKE HIS.
HE WAS TREATED IN PITTSBURGH'S
VA HOSPITAL SYSTEM, ONE OF THE
MOST HIGHLY REGARDED IN THE
NATION, AND THEY HAVE DIED
BECAUSE OF WHAT HE CAUGHT THERE,
LEGIONNAIRES' DISEASE, A
POTENTIALLY DEADLY BACTERIAL
INFECTION THAT SPREADS IN
CONTAMINATED WATER SUPPLIES.
AND WHAT MAKES THIS STORY EVEN
MORE TROUBLING IS THE EVIDENCE
THAT CNN HAS NOW UNCOVERED.
IT SHOWS THAT HOSPITAL OFFICIALS
KNEW ABOUT THE PROBLEM, AND YET
APPARENTLY, THEY FAILED TO FIX
IT.
BUT SINCE JANUARY OF LAST YEAR,
LAST YEAR, THERE HAVE BEEN AT
LEAST FIVE CASES DIRECTLY
TRACEABLE TO THE VA HOSPITAL
SYSTEM IN PITTSBURGH, BUT ONLY
LAST MONTH DID THE VA ADMIT THEY
HAD A PROBLEM WITH THEIR WATER
SUPPLY.
THEY SAID SO IN A NEWS RELEASE
AND ISSUED TWO MORE, INCLUDING
ONE THAT SAID THE PROBLEM HAS
BEEN SOLVED.
APART FROM NEWS RELEASES,
THOUGH, THEY'RE SIMPLY NOT
TALKING.
DREW GRIFFIN TONIGHT IS
INVESTIGATING.
>> WE FIRMLY BELIEVE THAT THE VA
WAS GOING TO GIVE HIM THE BEST
CARE THEY COULD POSSIBLY GIVE
HIM.
>> Reporter: KNOWING WHAT YOU
KNOW NOW, DID THE VA GIVE HIM
THE BEST CARE POSSIBLE?
>> NO, NO, THEY DIDN'T.
I MEAN, I CAN SAY THERE WAS
STRONG NEGLIGENCE ON THE VA'S
PART.
>> Reporter: BOB NICKLAS IS
TALKING ABOUT HIS FATHER, BILL,
A WORLD WAR II NAVY HERO WHO
WOULD DROP INTO HOSTILE WATERS
TO SAVE DOWNED NAVY PILOTS.
BUT BILL NICKLAS DIED THE DAY
AFTER THANKSGIVING FROM HEART
FAILURE AND LEGIONNAIRES'
DISEASE.
HE CONTRACTED IT FROM USING THE
WATER AT THE VA, WHICH WAS
CONTAMINATED WITH HIGH LEVELS OF
A BACTERIA KNOWN AS LEGIONELLA,
THE CAUSE OF LEGIONNAIRES'
DISEASE.
TWO OTHER FAMILIES ARE WONDERING
WHETHER THEIR VETERANS
CONTRACTED THE LEGIONNAIRES'
DISEASE THAT KILLED THEM FROM
THIS SAME PITTSBURGH VA.
CNN HAS NOW LEARNED THAT
HOSPITAL OFFICIALS KNEW THEY HAD
A PROBLEM WITH THE WATER SYSTEM
AS FAR BACK AS DECEMBER OF LAST
YEAR BUT CHOSE NOT TO REVEAL ANY
OF THAT PUBLICLY UNTIL A MONTH
AGO.
>> BEING A VETERAN MYSELF, I'M
SHOCKED AND APPALLED THAT THE VA
WOULD PUT, YOU KNOW, THEIR
VETERANS IN THAT TYPE OF
SITUATION.
>> Reporter: RECORDS OBTAINED BY
CNN SHOW THAT OVER THE PAST
YEAR, THE AMOUNT OF DISINFECTANT
IN THE VA'S WATER WAS LESS THAN
THE AMOUNT NEEDED TO PREVENT
LEGIONELLA BACTERIA FROM
REACHING DANGEROUS LEVELS.
AND INTERNAL RECORDS FROM A
WATER QUALITY COMPANY CALLED
LIQUITECH SHOW THAT IN DECEMBER
OF 2011, AN INFECTION FOUND THEY
HAVE LEGIONELLA.
"SYSTEMS ARE NOT BEING PROPERLY
MAINTAINED."
A SITE VISIT BY THE SAME COMPANY
FIVE MONTHS LATER FOUND THE
PROBLEMS CONTINUED, OBVIOUS
EVIDENCE THAT THE SYSTEMS HAD
NOT BEEN PROPERLY, REGULARLY
MAINTAINED.
LIQUITECH IS THE CONTRACTOR WHO
INSTALLED THE VA'S WATER SYSTEM
AND A SYSTEM LIKE IT IN HUNDREDS
OF OTHER HOSPITALS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY.
HE SAYS IT IS INEXPLICABLE THAT
THE VA HOSPITAL IN PITTSBURGH
KNEW IT HAD A PROBLEM, WAS
WARNED ABOUT IT, AND DID NOT FIX
IT.
>> THEY WERE NOT CLEANING THE
FLOW CELLS, THEY WERE NOT DOING
THE MONITORING, THEY WERE NOT
DOING THE THINGS THAT ARE
CRITICAL TO THE EFFICACY OF THE
SYSTEM.
>> Reporter: AND DID YOU TELL
THE HOSPITAL?
>> YES, WE DID.
YES, WE DID.
WE TOLD THEM -- WE ACTUALLY HAD
TWO AUDITS AND TOLD THEM TWICE
THAT THEY WERE DEFICIENT IN
THEIR MAINTENANCE.
>> Reporter: WHAT IS SO
FRUSTRATING TO SHIRA IS IF THE
SYSTEM HAD JUST BEEN MAINTAINED,
IF THE HOSPITAL HAD JUST
LISTENED AND MADE SIMPLE
ADJUSTMENTS, HE SAYS HE BELIEVES
LIVES COULD HAVE BEEN SAVED.
>> ABSOLUTELY, ABSOLUTELY.
>> Reporter: 100%?
>> 100%.
>> Reporter: AS IS DONE IN ALL
THE OTHER HOSPITALS THAT YOU
SERVE?
>> YES.
>> THIS OUTBREAK WAS ABSOLUTELY
PREVENTIBLE.
>> Reporter: DR. JANET STOUT
WITH HER COLLEAGUE, DR. VICTOR
YU, WORKED FOR MORE THAN 20
YEARS AT THIS SAME PITTSBURGH VA
HOSPIT RESEARCHING
LEGIONNAIRES' DISEASE.
THEY WERE PIONEERS IN THE FIELD
DEVELOPING THE COPPER SILVER
IONIZATION FILTRATION SYSTEM
WHICH IS STILL BEING USED AT
PITTSBURGH'S VA AND IN HOSPITALS
NATIONWIDE.
SIX YEARS AGO, IN A
CONTROVERSIAL MOVE, THE DOCTORS
AND THEIR LEGIONELLA RESEARCH
LAB WERE TOLD BY THE VA THEIR
SERVICES WERE NOT PRODUCTIVE AND
A DRAIN ON CLINICAL RESOURCES.
THE DOCTORS SAY FOR A DECADE
BEFORE THEY LEFT, NOT A SINGLE
PATIENT GOT LEGIONNAIRES FROM
THE HOSPITAL'S WATER.
SHE SAYS IF SHE WERE STILL
THERE, MONITORING THE WATER,
THIS ENTIRE TRAGEDY WOULD HAVE
BEEN PREVENTED WITH THE TURN OF
A KNOB.
>> SO, THIS IS NOT, YOU KNOW, AS
THEY SAY, ROCKET SCIENCE.
THIS IS STRAIGHT-FORWARD.
>> Reporter: SO, WHAT WENT
WRONG?
OUR CALLS AND E-MAILS TO THE VA
WENT UNANSWERED, SO KEEPING THEM
HONEST, WE WENT TO THE UNITED
STATES VETERANS ADMINISTRATION
HOSPITAL IN PITTSBURGH IN HOPES
OF GETTING ANSWERS.
WE WERE MET BY FOUR ARMED
FEDERAL OFFICERS.
HEY, HOW ARE YOU?
DREW GRIFFIN WITH CNN.
NICE TO SEE YOU.
>> VA POLICE.
>> YES, SIR.
>> THIS HAS NOT BEEN APPROVED BY
OUR PUBLIC AFFAIRS OFFICE.
I CANNOT ALLOW YOU INSIDE.
>> I'M CALLING PUBLIC AFFAIRS
RIGHT NOW.
DO YOU WANT TO CALL THEM AND SEE
IF THEY CAN COME ON?
>> I CANNOT TECHNICALLY CALL
THEM.
CAN YOU TAKE THE CAMERA BACK
ACROSS THE STREET UNTIL WE HAVE
AUTHORIZATION?
>> Reporter: HOLD ON, I'M ON THE
PHONE NOW.
AGAIN AFTER REACHING AN
ANSWERING MACHINE, THEY ASKED US
TO LEAVE.
WHO TOLD YOU TO KICK US OFF?
>> IT'S OUR POLICY.
>> Reporter: YOUR POLICY?
WE CANNOT STAND ON UNITED STATES
GOVERNMENT LAND WITH A CAMERA?
>> WITHOUT LEGITIMATE PURPOSE TO
BE HERE.
>> Reporter: WITHOUT LEGITIMATE
PURPOSE?
I'M TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHY
THESE PATIENTS DIED.
>> AND BEING NEWS MEDIA WHILE
REPORTING, I HAVE TO ASK YOU TO
LEAVE UNTIL APPROVED BY OUR
PUBLIC AFFAIRS OFFICE.
>> Reporter: INSTEAD OF
ANSWERING OUR QUESTIONS, THE VA
SPOKESPERSON DAVID COWGILL
RELEASED THREE PUBLIC
ADVISORIES.
THE LAST ONE ON THE DAY WE LEFT
IN A VOICE MAIL.
>> VA IS COMMITTED TO PROVIDING
SAFE FACILITIES AND QUALITY CARE
FOR VETERANS.
>> Reporter: IT GOES ON TO SAY
THAT AN INVESTIGATION IS UNDER
WAY AND THAT --
>> TESTING RESULTS INDICATE
REMEDIATION AT THE PITTSBURGH
VAMC UNIVERSITY DRIVE HAS BEEN
SUCCESSFUL.
>> Reporter: BILL NICKLAS'S FLAG
STILL FLIES ON THE FRONT LAWN
THAT HE MOWED HIMSELF.
HE WOULD HAVE TURNED 88 THIS
PAST WEEKEND.
INSTEAD OF CELEBRATING HIS
BIRTHDAY, HIS FAMILY HELD A
MEMORIAL SERVICE.
>> THEY SHOULD HAVE THE BEST AND
UTMOST CARE THAT ANYBODY ELSE,
EVEN BETTER THAN THE NORMAL
CIVILIAN.
I MEAN, THEY FOUGHT FOR THEIR
COUNTRY, YOU KNOW, THEY GO TO
BATTLE, THEY, YOU KNOW, THEY
LOVE THEIR COUNTRY AND WHERE DO
THEY GO?
THEY GO TO A HOSPITAL AND THEY
BASICALLY DIE IN THERE.
>> Reporter: ANDERSON, LET ME
TELL YOU A LITTLE BIT MORE ABOUT
BILL NICKLAS.
THIS GUY DRAFTED AT 17 YEARS OLD
INTO THE U.S. NAVY.
HE WOULD DRIVE 30 MILES OUT OF
HIS WAY, PAST TWO OTHER
HOSPITALS, JUST TO GO TO THE VA
BECAUSE HE THOUGHT HE WOULD GET
BETTER CARE THERE AS A VETERAN,
WHICH IS WHY HIS SONS REALLY
FEEL LET DOWN BY THIS.
>> WE KNOW OF THREE POSSIBLE
DEATHS DUE TO THIS LEGIONELLA AT
THE HOSPITAL, BUT THERE ACTUALLY
COULD BE MORE DEATHS, RIGHT?
>> Reporter: CERTAINLY.
ALL THE INFORMATION ON THESE
CASES, 29 CASES, IS COMING FROM
THE HOSPITAL.
THIS HAS BEEN GOING ON FOR A
YEAR NOW, ANDERSON.
I THINK A LOT OF HEALTH CARE
PROFESSIONALS, A LOT OF
FAMILIES, QUITE FRANKLY, ARE
GOING TO LOOK BACK OVER THIS
YEAR, LOOK BACK AT THE FAMILY
MEMBERS THEY MAY HAVE LOST AND
BEGIN ASKING QUESTIONS ABOUT
WHAT THIS WAS THAT KILLED THEIR
LOVED ONE.
COULD IT HAVE BEEN THIS
LEGIONNAIRES' DISEASE?
>> AND WHO BESIDES US ARE TRYING
TO GET ANSWERS ON THIS, AND IS
THE VA STILL REFUSING TO TALK TO
YOU?
>> Reporter: YEAH, THEY WILL NOT
COME OUT.
AS YOU SAW IN THAT PIECE, THEY
WILL NOT TALK TO US AT ALL.
THEY REFERRED US TO THE
WASHINGTON PR DIVISION, SENT US
RIGHT BACK TO PITTSBURGH.
IT'S BEEN A MESS.
BUT THE CENTERS FOR DISEASE
CONTROL AND PREVENTION, THEY DID
SEND A TEAM THERE IN NOVEMBER TO
INVESTIGATE THIS.
WE'RE TOLD THAT THE
INVESTIGATION, THE RESULTS FROM
THE CDC WILL GO TO THE VA IN
COMING WEEKS.
WE'RE NOT SURE IF THAT'S GOING
TO BE RELEASED TO THE PUBLIC.
>> AND I STILL CAN'T UNDERSTAND
WHY THE VA DID NOTHING WHEN THEY
KNEW THEY HAD A PROBLEM.
>> Reporter: ACTUALLY, ANDERSON,
WE FOUND OUT THAT ABOUT SIX
MONTHS AGO, THE VA DID BRING IN
A CONSULTANT WHO MADE
RECOMMENDATIONS ON HOW TO FIX
THE WATER, BUT THE VA APPARENTLY
DID NOT TELL THAT CONSULTANT
THAT THEY HAD LEGIONNAIRES CASES
AT THE HOSPITAL.
IF THEY HAD TOLD THE CONSULTANTS
THAT, THERE WOULD HAVE BEEN
DIFFERENT RECOMMENDATIONS, THE
VA WOULD HAVE BEEN TOLD TO
HANDLE IT DIFFERENTLY, AND WE
JUST DON'T KNOW WHY, BECAUSE THE
VA WON'T TALK TO US.
>> UNBELIEVABLE.
DREW, APPRECIATE IT.
THANKS.
>>> WELL, A CNN EXCLUSIVE AHEAD.
A TRULY BREATHTAKING DISPLAY OF
COURAGE BY A SYRIAN TEENAGER.
HE RISKED HIS LIFE TO SAVE A
STRANGER, AN OLD WOMAN WHO WAS
HIT BY A SNIPER.
THAT'S HIM CRAWLING ALONG THE
GROUND TRYING TO RESCUE THIS
LADY.
ARWA DAMON'S REPORT IS NEXT.
UPSIDE DOWN.
>> HI. >> HI.
YOU KNOW, I CAN SAVE YOU
15% TODAY IF YOU OPEN UP
A CHARGE CARD ACCOUNT WITH US.
>> YOU JUST READ MY MIND.
>> Announcer: JUST ONE LITTLE
PIECE OF INFORMATION AND THEY
CAN OPEN BOGUS ACCOUNTS,
STEALING YOUR CREDIT, YOUR MONEY
AND RUINING YOUR REPUTATION.
THAT'S WHY YOU NEED LIFELOCK
TO RELENTLESSLY PROTECT
WHAT MATTERS MOST...
[BEEPING...]
HELPING STOP CROOKS BEFORE
YOUR IDENTITY IS ATTACKED.
AND NOW YOU CAN HAVE THE MOST
COMPREHENSIVE IDENTITY THEFT
PROTECTION AVAILABLE TODAY...
LIFELOCK ULTIMATE.
SO FOR PROTECTION YOU JUST
CAN'T GET ANYWHERE ELSE,
GET LIFELOCK ULTIMATE.
>> I DIDN'T KNOW HOW SERIOUS
IDENTITY THEFT WAS
UNTIL I LOST MY CREDIT AND
EVENTUALLY I LOST MY HOME.
>> Announcer: CREDIT MONITORING
IS NOT ENOUGH, BECAUSE IT TELLS
YOU AFTER THE FACT, SOMETIMES
AS MUCH AS 30 DAYS LATER.
WITH LIFELOCK, AS SOON AS OUR
NETWORK SPOTS A THREAT TO YOUR
IDENTITY, YOU'LL GET A PROACTIVE
RISK ALERT, PROTECTING YOU
BEFORE YOU BECOME A VICTIM.
>> IDENTITY THEFT WAS A HUGE,
HUGE PROBLEM FOR ME AND IT'S
GONE AWAY BECAUSE OF LIFELOCK.
>> Announcer: WHILE NO ONE CAN
STOP ALL IDENTITY THEFT,
IF CRIMINALS DO STEAL
YOUR INFORMATION, LIFELOCK
WILL HELP FIX IT, WITH OUR
$1 MILLION SERVICE GUARANTEE.
DON'T WAIT UNTIL YOU BECOME
THE NEXT VICTIM.
YOU HAVE SO MUCH TO PROTECT
AND NOTHING TO LOSE WHEN YOU
CALL LIFELOCK NOW TO GET TWO
FULL MONTHS OF IDENTITY THEFT
PROTECTION RISK FREE.
THAT'S RIGHT, 60 DAYS RISK-FREE.
USE PROMO CODE: GETHELP.
IF YOU'RE NOT COMPLETELY
SATISFIED, NOTIFY LIFELOCK
AND YOU WON'T PAY A CENT.
ORDER NOW AND ALSO GET THIS
SHREDDER TO KEEP YOUR DOCUMENTS
OUT OF THE WRONG HANDS--
A $29 DOLLAR VALUE, FREE.
GET PROTECTED NOW.
CALL THE NUMBER ON YOUR SCREEN
OR GO TO LIFELOCK.COM TO TRY
LIFELOCK PROTECTION RISK FREE
FOR A FULL 60 DAYS.
USE PROMO CODE: GETHELP.
PLUS GET THIS DOCUMENT SHREDDER
FREE-- BUT ONLY IF YOU
ACT RIGHT NOW.
CALL THE NUMBER ON YOUR SCREEN
NOW!
>>> TWO CHILDREN KILLED, A
BROTHER AND SISTER JUST 3 AND 5
YEARS OLD, EACH STABBED MORE
THAN A DOZEN TIMES.
THEIR KILLER, THEIR OWN FATHER,
WHO WAS A DOCTOR.
HE IS NOW A FREE MAN.
WE'LL TELL YOU WHY, COMING UP.
>>> TONIGHT, A "360" EXCLUSIVE
FROM SYRIA.
AN EXTRAORDINARY DISPLAY OF
BRAVERY IN A SNIPER'S ALLEY WITH
BULLETS FLYING.
A TEENAGE BOY WHO RISKED HIS
LIFE SAYS HE'S NO HERO, THAT HE
DID WHAT COUNTLESS OTHERS DO
EVERY DAY.
WE'RE GOING TO SHOW YOU THAT IN
A MOMENT.
>>> FIRST, NEW SIGNS THAT DEFEAT
COULD BE NEAR FOR AL ASSAD'S
REGIME.
TODAY RUSSIA, SYRIA'S MOST
POWERFUL ALLY, SAID ASSAD'S
LOSING CONTROL OF HIS COUNTRY
AND ADMITTED THE OPPOSITION
COULD WIN.
NATO'S LEADER WENT FURTHER,
SAYING THE REGIME IS APPROACHING
COLLAPSE.
THEIR COMMENTS CAME AS
OPPOSITION GROUPS SEIZED A
MILITARY BASE NEAR DAMASCUS.
MEANTIME, SYRIAN STATE
TELEVISION SAID AT LEAST TWO
DOZEN CIVILIANS WERE KILLED IN
TWO CAR BOMBINGS OUTSIDE OF
DAMASCUS.
SEVEN CHILDREN WERE SAID TO BE
AMONG THOSE KILLED IN THIS
BLAST.
IN A NEARBY TOWN, EIGHT PEOPLE,
MOSTLY WOMEN AND CHILDREN, WERE
REPORTED KILLED IN THIS BOMBING
ACCORDING TO STATE TELEVISION.
TONIGHT, ASSAD SHOWS NO OUTWARD
SIGNS OF BACKING DOWN, HOWEVER,
AND IN HOTSPOTS LIKE ALEPPO,
CIVILIANS ARE STILL DYING IN THE
CROSS FIRE.
NOW THAT ACT OF INCREDIBLE
COURAGE THAT WAS CAUGHT ON TAPE.
HERE IS ARWA DAMON'S EXCLUSIVE
REPORT.
>> Reporter: A FIGHTER SLITHERS
ACROSS THE STREET, HIS BODY
COVERED.
YARDS AWAY A WOMAN LIES
MOTIONLESS.
SHE'S BEEN SHOT BY A SNIPER.
HER RESCUER IS NOT A RELATIVE,
NOR A NEIGHBOR.
HE'S NEVER MET HER.
ABDULLAH FAHAN IS JUST 17.
HE KNEW HE HAD TO SAVE THE WOMAN
OR DIE TRYING.
WHEN WE MET HIM LATER, HE TELLS
US --
"WE HAD A FEELING THAT SHE WAS
STILL ALIVE.
WE WANTED TO SAVE HER, TO GET
HER TO A HOSPITAL."
AS HE CRAWLS CLOSER, HE CAN SEE
HER HAND.
HER FINGERS SHAKING.
"COVER HIM!
COVER HIM," SOMEONE SHOUTS.
OTHER FIGHTERS LAY DOWN COVER
FIRE.
ABDULLAH QUICKLY TIES THE HOSE
TO HER LEGS, BUT HE'S UNABLE TO
RETREAT.
"I SAID TO MYSELF, IF I DIE,
IT'S GOD'S WILL THAT I DIE NEXT
TO THIS WOMAN," HE TELLS US.
FINALLY, HE MAKES A RUN FOR IT,
AND THE REBELS DRAG THE WOMAN
BACK.
[ GUNFIRE ]
>> Reporter: THE WOMAN AND HER
SON WERE WALKING RIGHT DOWN THE
STREET THERE.
REBEL FIGHTERS SHOUTED AT THEM
TO STAY AWAY, BUT IT WAS TOO
LATE.
ALEPPO IS CRISSCROSSED WITH
SIMILAR SNIPER ALLEYS.
SOME ARE KNOWN, BUT OTHERS DO
NOT REVEAL THEMSELVES UNTIL THE
FIRST SHOT HAS BEEN FIRED.
DESPITE ABDULLAH'S EFFORTS, THE
WOMAN DIES.
HER SON UTTERLY DISTRAUGHT.
>> Reporter: "DON'T DIE NOW,
DON'T DIE TODAY," HE PLEADS.
"ANSWER ME, MOM, ANSWER ME!
SHE'S NOT DEAD.
SHE'S NOT DEAD," HE SAYS, AS HE
COLLAPSES.
ABDULLAH IS LEFT WONDERING
WHETHER HER LIFE COULD HAVE BEEN
SAVED IF HE'D REACHED HER
SOONER.
UNTIL RECENTLY, HE WORKED AT A
BAKERY.
NOW, LIKE THOUSANDS OF YOUNG
SYRIANS, HE PUTS HIS LIFE ON THE
LINE.
"I AM NOT A HERO.
I AM JUST LIKE ANYONE ELSE,"
ABDULLAH TELLS US.
AND WE'RE LEFT TO WONDER, HOW
MANY SIMILAR ACTS OF COURAGE GO
UNRECORDED EVERY DAY IN SYRIA,
AND HOW MANY INNOCENTS ARE LOST?
ARWA DAMON, CNN, ALEPPO.
>> ARWA DAMON REPORTING.
THERE'S A LOT MORE HAPPENING
TONIGHT.
ISHA'S HERE WITH A "360
BULLETIN."
>>> THE TALIBAN HAS TAKEN CREDIT
FOR A SUICIDE BOMBING IN
AFGHANISTAN THAT KILLED AT LEAST
THREE PEOPLE, INCLUDING ONE
AMERICAN.
THE ATTACK HAPPENED NEAR
KANDAHAR'S AIR FIELD JUST HOURS
AFTER U.S. DEFENSE SECRETARY
LEON PANETTA LEFT THE CITY.
>>> FOR THE FIRST TIME WE'RE
GETTING A LOOK AT NORTH KOREA'S
FIRST APPARENT SUCCESSFUL LAUNCH
OF A LONG-RANGE MISSILE,
COURTESY OF THE STATE-RUN NEWS
AGENCY.
THE COUNTRY'S LEADER, KIM
JONG-UN, CELEBRATED WITH
SOLDIERS.
>>> THE REMAINS OF MUSIC STAR
JENNI RIVERA HAVE BEEN
IDENTIFIED AND RETURNED TO HER
FAMILY.
RIVERA AND SIX OTHERS ARE
BELIEVED TO HAVE DIED IN
SUNDAY'S PLANE CRASH IN MEXICO.
THE CAUSE OF THE CRASH IS UNDER
INVESTIGATION.
>>> AND TWO MEN ARRESTED IN A
MURDER-FOR-HIRE PLOT WERE
PLANNING ON CASTRATING AND
KILLING JUSTIN BIEBER.
THAT'S ACCORDING TO POLICE IN
NEW MEXICO AND VERMONT.
THE SUSPECTS, A CONVICTED FELON
AND HIS 23-YEAR-OLD NEPHEW, WERE
ALLEGEDLY HIRED BY AN INMATE IN
NEW MEXICO INFATUATED WITH THE
POP MUSIC STAR.
ANDERSON?
>> ISHA, THANKS.
>>> MUCH MORE AHEAD, INCLUDING A
MOTHER'S GRIEF AND OUTRAGE.
HER YOUNG SON AND DAUGHTER WERE
VICIOUSLY STABBED TO DEATH BY
THEIR OWN FATHER.
HE CONFESSED, BUT NOW HE'S FREE.
COMING UP, HIS EX-WIFE'S FIGHT
TO MAKE SURE NO OTHER FAMILY
SUFFERS WHAT SHE HAS ENDURED.
>>> HER DEATH SHOCKED THE WORLD,
NOW BRITISH POLICE ARE RELEASING
NEW INFORMATION ABOUT THE NURSE
WHO APPARENTLY TOOK HER OWN LIFE
AFTER TRANSFERRING A PRANK CALL
TO THE WARD TREATING CATHERINE,
THE DUCHESS OF CAMBRIDGE.
WHAT THEY'RE SAYING ABOUT THE
CIRCUMSTANCES SURROUNDING HER
DEATH.
>>> CRIME AND PUNISHMENT.
A MOTHER WHOSE YOUNG CHILDREN
WERE VICIOUSLY STABBED TO DEATH
IS REELING TONIGHT.
THEIR KILLER IS BACK ON THE
STREETS.
HE WAS RELEASED FROM A MENTAL
HEALTH FACILITY JUST YESTERDAY.
THE CASE IS AS CONTROVERSIAL AS
IT IS HORRIFYING.
5-YEAR-OLD OLIVIER AND HIS
3-YEAR-OLD SISTER ANN SOPHIE
WERE STABBED TO DEATH IN THEIR
OWN BEDS.
EACH CHILD HAD MORE THAN A DOZEN
WOUNDS.
AS HORRIBLE AS THOSE FACTS ALONE
ARE, IT GETS WORSE.
THEIR FATHER, A PHYSICIAN, IS
THE ONE WHO KILLED THEM AND HE
CONFESSED.
BUT A CANADIAN JURY RULED THAT
HE WASN'T CRIMINALLY RESPONSIBLE
BECAUSE OF HIS MENTAL STATE AT
THE TIME.
INSTEAD OF PRISON, HE WAS SENT
TO A MENTAL HEALTH FACILITY.
NOW HE'S FREE AND HE HAS NO
CRIMINAL RECORD.
HIS EX-WIFE, WHO'S ALSO A
DOCTOR, FOUGHT HARD TO KEEP THAT
FROM HAPPENING.
PAULA NEWTON HAS MORE.
>> Reporter: AS ISABEL GASTON
POURS OVER HER OWN CHILDREN'S
AUTOPSY REPORTS, SHE WISHES SHE
HAD NO IDEA WHAT THEY MEANT.
BUT AS A PHYSICIAN AND A
CORONER, SHE KNOWS IT'S TRUE.
HER CHILDREN SUFFERED LONG,
GRUESOME DEATHS.
>> I KNEW THAT IT WAS NOT A
SHORT DEATH.
MY LITTLE BOY RECEIVED 20 -- 20
STABS OF A KNIFE.
HE HAD SEVEN MARKS OF DEFENSE.
HE HAD NO WOUND THAT WAS THE ONE
THAT GAVE HIM DEATH.
>> THERE WAS NO MERCY?
>> NO.
MY LITTLE GIRL HAD 19 WOUNDS.
MAYBE SHE WAS LUCKIER BECAUSE
SHE HAD ONE THAT WAS MORE MORTAL
THAN THE OTHER, BUT SHE FELT THE
19 SHOTS FOR SURE.
>> Reporter: BUT THIS WAS NO
RANDOM ACT OF VIOLENCE.
THE KNIFE WAS WIELDED BY THE
CHILDREN'S FATHER AND GASTON'S
EX-HUSBAND, CARDIOLOGIST DR. GUY
TURCOTTE.
>> TO KNOW THAT MY CHILDREN
FACED THE PERSON THAT THEY
SHOULD TRUST THE MOST AND THEY
WERE LEFT BY THEMSELVES TO DIE,
NO ONE HOLDING THEIR HAND, I
STRUGG
STRUGGLE, OKAY.
I STRUGGLE ALL THE DAY, EVERY
DAY OF MY LIFE, AND UNTIL I DIE
I WILL STRUGGLE.
>> Reporter: DR. TURCOTTE ADMITS
HE KILLED HIS CHILDREN IN 2009,
AND YET NOW HE IS A FREE MAN,
EVEN POSSIBLY FREE TO PRACTICE
MEDICINE AGAIN.
IN 2010, A CANADIAN JURY FAILED
TO CONVICT TURCOTTE OF THE
MURDERS, FINDING HIM NOT
CRIMINALLY RESPONSIBLE DUE TO
MENTAL ILLNESS.
DR. TURCOTTE KILLED HIS CHILDREN
ON WHAT WAS SUPPOSED TO BE A
FAMILY MOVIE NIGHT.
THIS SURVEILLANCE VIDEO SHOWS
HIM RENTING VIDEOS WITH HIS
CHILDREN JUST HOURS BEFORE HE
BRUTALLY STABBED THEM IN THEIR
BEDS.
THESE WERE TROUBLING TIMES FOR
DR. TURCOTTE.
HE WAS SEPARATED FROM HIS WIFE.
SHE HAD LEFT HIM FOR ANOTHER
MAN.
DR. TURCOTTE SAYS HE SUFFERED A
BLACKOUT AND DOES NOT REMEMBER
STABBING THE CHILDREN.
THE VERDICT IS BEING APPEALED.
DO YOU BELIEVE HE WAS MENTALLY
INSANE WHEN HE COMMITTED THE
MURDERS, AND DO YOU BELIEVE HE'S
MENTALLY INSANE NOW?
>> NO, NO.
>> Reporter: WHY?
>> WHY SHOULD I, THAT I DON'T
ACCEPT HE IS MENTALLY ILL, WHEN
I LOOK AT THE FACTS, OKAY.
WE HAVE A PERSON THAT'S A
CARDIOLOGIST THAT HAS NEVER HAD
A PSYCHIATRIC INCIDENT, NEVER,
NOT AT ALL.
>> Reporter: THE JURY, THOUGH,
BELIEVED THE TESTIMONY OF TWO
PSYCHIATRISTS PRESENTED BY THE
DEFENSE.
THEY TESTIFIED THAT DR. TURCOTTE
COULD NOT HAVE KNOWN WHAT HE WAS
DOING WHEN HE REPEATEDLY STABBED
5-YEAR-OLD OLIVIER AND
3-YEAR-OLD ANN SOPHIE.
>> I'M A LITTLE BIT MAD BECAUSE
YOU KNOW, I HAVE TO RESPECT
THEIR DECISION.
SO, IT CONFRONTS ME AND MY
VALUES, BUT I THINK THEY DIDN'T
DO THEIR JOB.
>> Reporter: DR. TURCOTTE IS NOW
A FREE MAN WITH NO CRIMINAL
RECORD, AND HE SAYS HE'S NOT
TAKING ANY MEDICATION FOR MENTAL
ILLNESS.
THE ONLY CONDITIONS OF HIS
RELEASE ARE THAT HE CONTINUE
WITH THERAPY AND STAY AWAY FROM
HIS EX-WIFE AND HER FAMILY.
HE MUST ALSO GO BEFORE THE
REVIEW PANEL THAT RELEASED HIM
IN A YEAR.
THE MEDICAL PROFESSIONALS
CURRENTING TREATING TURCOTTE AND
THE PSYCHIATRIC EXPERTS WHO GAVE
TESTIMONY AT HIS TRIAL HAVE TOLD
CNN THEY DO NOT WISH TO COMMENT
ON THE CASE.
DR. GASTON SAYS SHE FEARS FOR
HER LIFE NOW, AND BELIEVES THE
PSYCHIATRISTS THAT TESTIFIED ON
HIS BEHALF DID NOT EVALUATE HIM
LONG ENOUGH.
SHE IS CALLING FOR STRICTER
GUIDELINES WHEN PSYCHIATRIC
TESTIMONY IS PRESENTED IN COURT.
SHE SAYS SHE HAS NEVER BELIEVED
HER EX-HUSBAND WAS MENTALLY ILL,
AND EVEN IF HE WAS, HE COULD NOT
NOW BE CURED IN LITTLE MORE THAN
THREE YEARS.
>> WHAT I'M SAYING, I HAVE
QUESTION.
I'M A MOTHER BUT I'M ALSO A
DOCTOR.
>> Reporter: YOU HOPE IT WILL
HELP OTHER VICTIMS IN THE
FUTURE?
>> YES, I HOPE.
AND YOU KNOW WHAT, I'M VERY
CONVINCED AND I'M WILLING TO
LOSE MY HEALTH, I'M WILLING TO
LOSE MY ECONOMY STATUS, I'M
WILLING TO LOSE MY PROFESSIONAL
STATUS, I'M WILLING TO LOSE MY
LIFE.
I'M WILLING TO GO VERY FAR IN
THIS BATTLE.
AND I'M REALLY, REALLY CONVINCED
THAT IT HAS TO CHANGE.
>> Reporter: DID YOU EVER ASK
HIM WHY HE DID IT?
>> I WANTED TO ASK HIM, BUT, YOU
KNOW, THE RESPONSE THAT HE'S
GOING TO GIVE ME, IF HE DOESN'T
TELL ME THE TRUTH, THAT IS MY
TRUTH THAT I KNOW IS FOR
VENGEANCE, YOU KNOW, HE WILL
INVENT EVERYTHING, AND THAT'S
WHAT HE DID IN COURT, YOU KNOW?
>> Reporter: AND DR. GASTON SAYS
SHE BELIEVES IT WILL BE AN
IMPORTANT TEST CASE TO POSSIBLY
LIMIT CLAIMS OF MENTAL INSANITY
AND BETTER SCRUTINIZE THE
MEDICAL EVIDENCE NEEDED TO PROVE
IT.
>> THAT IS SUCH A HORRIFIC
CRIME.
PAULA NEWTON JOINS ME NOW.
PAULA, WHAT'S BEEN THE REACTION
TO THIS RELEASE?
>> Reporter: OUTRAGE REALLY
THROUGHOUT THE COUNTRY, FELT
MOST ACUTELY HERE IN MONTREAL
TODAY, ANDERSON.
EVERYONE WAS TALKING ABOUT IT.
THE OUTRAGE STEMS FROM TWO
THING.
ONE OF THE THINGS IN THE
HEADLINES, LOOK, ANDERSON, THIS
GUY STABBED HIS CHILDREN 46
TIMES, HE CONFESSED TO IT.
HE SERVED 46 MONTHS, NOT ALL OF
IT IN PRISON.
HE IS A FREE MAN RIGHT NOW.
ADD TO THAT THAT THE MENTAL
FACILITY ACTUALLY SAID, LOOK,
THIS GUY DOES PRESENT A RISK TO
SOCIETY.
WE DON'T KNOW HOW HE'LL BEHAVE
IN THE FUTURE, BUT HE NEEDS TO
BE FREE AND WE CAN MANAGE THAT
RISK.
ANDERSON, I'LL REMIND YOU, THERE
WILL BE NO POLICE OFFICER
FOLLOWING HIM AROUND, NOT
ANYTHING LIKE THAT, AND THE
PUBLIC WANTS TO KNOW WHY.
>> I MEAN, THAT'S JUST
INCREDIBLE.
AND FOR SUCH A SHORT AMOUNT OF
TIME THAT HE ACTUALLY WAS IN
THIS MENTAL HEALTH FACILITY.
WHAT IS NEXT FOR HIM?
>> Reporter: WELL, THIS IS THE
OTHER OUTRAGEOUS THING PEOPLE
ARE TELLING ME.
IN HIS TESTIMONY AS TO WHY HE
WANTED TO BE RELEASED, HE SAID
HE WANTED TO LEAD A NORMAL LIFE.
ANDERSON, HE'S GOING TO APPLY
AGAIN TO PRACTICE MEDICINE.
HE IS A CARDIOLOGIST.
HE DOESN'T HAVE ANY COMPLAINTS
AGAINST HIM IN TERMS OF THE KIND
OF CARE HE HAD FOR HIS PARENTS.
PATIENTS.
HE IS FREE TO BE A DOCTOR AGAIN
IF HE GETS LICENSED ONCE MORE.
AND AGAIN, THE ONLY THING THAT
THE MOTHER, ISABELLE GASTON
KEEPS RELYING UPON IS AN APPEAL
IN THE NEW YEAR.
>> THAT'S JUST EXTRAORDINARY.
PAULA NEWTON WILL CONTINUE TO
FOLLOW IT.
THANK YOU.
>>> STILL AHEAD, A MURDER
MYSTERY WITH A TWIST.
DOLPHINS ARE TURNING UP DEAD
ALONG THE GULF COAST BUT WHO OR
WHAT IS KILLING THEM?
ED LAVANDERA HAS A SPECIAL
REPORT AHEAD.
>>> MURDER MYSTERY ALONG THE
GULF COAST IS DEEPENING TONIGHT.
MUTILATED BODIES OF DOLPHINS
HAVE BEEN WASHING ASHORE ALL
YEAR.
IN RECENT WEEKS THE PACE HAS
PICKED UP DRAMATICALLY.
AS MANY AS TEN DEAD DOLPHINS
HAVE BEEN FOUND.
THE DISCOVERY IS GRUESOME,
DISTURBING AND FRANKLY BAFFLING.
COULD IT BE THE WORK OF SOME
KIND OF A SERIAL KILLER?
IF SO, WHY WOULD ANYONE WANT TO
HARM DOLPHINS?
THAT'S WHAT A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE
WONDERING TONIGHT.
THE RACE TO SOLVE THE MYSTERY
HAS BEEN INTENSIFYING.
ED LAVANDERA REPORTS.
>> GOOD TO GO.
>> Reporter: THE HUNT IS ON.
>> WE'RE GOING TO DO A ROUTINE
SAFETY CHECK.
>> Reporter: FOR A DOLPHIN
KILLER.
THE DOLPHIN CASE IS IN THE BACK
OF YOUR MIND?
>> RIGHT.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO COME OUT AND
ASK HIM ARE YOU SHOOTING
DOLPHINS.
>> PERMISSION TO COME ON BOARD?
>> WE'RE GOING TO LOOK AND SEE
IF THERE'S ANY EVIDENCE AS FAR
AS FIREARMS AND SUCH LIKE THAT.
>> FIREARMS?
GUNS?
>> Reporter: OFFICER LEO
DEGEORGE AND A MISSISSIPPI
MARINE PATROL UNIT ARE SEARCHING
ANY BOAT THEY CAN FIND, TRYING
TO UNRAVEL THE MYSTERIOUS AND
DISTURBING CASE OF MURDERED
DOLPHINS WASHING UP ALONG THE
GULF COAST.
>> I'M GOING TO GO DOWN BELOW
AND TAKE A LOOK, SEE WHAT I CAN
FIND OUT.
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> Reporter: THERE'S A GROWING
SENSE OF URGENCY.
BETWEEN JANUARY AND NOVEMBER OF
THIS YEAR, SEVEN SLAIN DOLPHINS
HAVE BEEN FOUND.
BUT IN THE LAST TWO WEEKS, TWO
MORE DOLPHINS AND A PART OF A
THIRD WASHED ASHORE.
SOME HAVE BEEN SHOT, SOME
MUTILATED WITH TAILS AND A JAW
CUT OFF.
ONLY THE HEAD OF ONE DOLPHIN WAS
RECENTLY FOUND ON A BEACH.
MANY PICTURES TOO GRUESOME TO
SHOW.
>> SO THE ONE THING IT ALL HAS
IN COMMON IS ALL THESE DOLPHINS
HAVE TURNED UP ALONG THESE
LITTLE BARRIER ISLANDS ALONG THE
GULF COAST?
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
>> Reporter: MOABY SALIANI IS
THE LEAD BIOLOGIST AT THE
INSTITUTE FOR MARINE MAMMAL
STUDIES IN GULFPORT,
MISSISSIPPI.
HE'S ANALYZED THE CORPSES OF ALL
THE DOLPHINS FOR FEDERAL
INVESTIGATORS AT NOAA, THE
NATIONAL OCEANIC AND ATMOSPHERIC
ADMINISTRATION.
THERE NOW COULD BE AS MANY AS
TEN MURDERED DOLPHINS, THE
MAJORITY DISCOVERED IN THE LAST
TWO MONTHS.
WHAT DO YOU TAKE AWAY FROM ALL
THAT?
>> WELL, IT LOOKS LIKE SOMEBODY
IS DERANGED.
IT'S REALLY SENSELESS.
IT'S REPUGNANT, IT'S ILLEGAL.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND WHAT TYPE OF
PERSON WOULD DO SUCH A CRUEL
ACT.
>> Reporter: WHEN WE FIRST
STARTED ASKING QUESTIONS ABOUT
THE DEAD DOLPHINS A FEW WEEKS
AGO, WE ASKED FEDERAL
INVESTIGATORS IF THEY THOUGHT
THIS COULD BE THE WORK OF A
DOLPHIN SERIAL KILLER OR
KILLERS.
THEY TOLD US THEN THAT THAT WAS
NOT ONE OF THEIR THEORIES, BUT
SINCE THEN, THREE MORE DOLPHINS
HAVE WASHED ASHORE, AND THOSE
FEDERAL INVESTIGATORS NOW SAY
THEY CAN'T COMMENT ON AN ACTIVE
CRIMINAL INVESTIGATION.
YOU'VE SEEN THESE ANIMALS UP
CLOSE.
WERE YOU ABLE TO SEE ANYTHING
THAT KIND OF LEADS YOU TO
BELIEVE THAT IT MIGHT HAVE BEEN
THE WORK OF ONE PERSON?
>> WELL, IT'S REALLY HARD FOR US
TO DO, BECAUSE ALL WE CAN DO AS
SCIENTISTS IS REPORT THE FACT,
THE INVESTIGATIVE AGENCIES AND
PEOPLE WHO ARE TRAINED TO
DETERMINE WHAT KIND OF
CONNECTIONS AND WHAT TYPE OF
PROFILE A PERSON HAS.
>> Reporter: FEDERAL
INVESTIGATORS TOLD US A FEW
WEEKS AGO THEY THINK THE MURDERS
ARE NOT CONNECTED.
BUT ALONG THIS COASTLINE TODAY,
MANY PEOPLE ARE WONDERING IF
THERE'S A DERANGED DOLPHIN
SERIAL KILLER OR KILLERS HUNTING
THESE BELOVED CREATURES.
ON PATROL, WILD DOLPHINS BOB UP
AND DOWN ALL AROUND US.
THE MYSTERIOUS STRING OF DOLPHIN
KILLINGS IS SOMETHING THESE
OFFICERS HAVE NEVER SEEN.
WHAT'S YOUR BIGGEST FEAR ABOUT
THE WAY ALL OF THIS IS PLAYING
OUT?
>> THE BIGGEST FEAR?
MORE OF THEM.
AND WHY WOULD SOMEBODY DO THIS?
I DON'T KNOW HOW THEY'RE GETTING
A THRILL OUT OF THIS.
>> Reporter: AND THE SEARCH
INTENSIFIES FOR A PREDATOR
LURKING AROUND THESE WATERS.
ED LAVANDERA, CNN, ON THE
MISSISSIPPI SOUND.
>>> WELL, NOW ISHA JOINS US
AGAIN WITH THE "360 NEWS AND
BUSINESS BULLETIN."
ISHA?
>>> ANDERSON, BRITISH POLICE SAY
THE APPARENT SUICIDE OF THE
NURSE WHO TRANSFERRED A PRANK
CALL TO THE WARD TREATING
CATHERINE DUCHESS OF CAMBRIDGE
IS NOT SUSPICIOUS.
THEY SAY A CO-WORKER FOUND HER
HANGING IN THE HOSPITAL'S LIVING
QUARTERS.
SHE LEFT THREE SUICIDE NOTES BUT
POLICE ARE NOT REVEALING THEIR
CONTENT.
SOFTWARE NINEER JOHN McAFEE IS
BACK IN THE U.S. AFTER HE SAYS
HE WAS DEPORTED FROM GUATEMALA.
McAFEE ENTERED THE COUNTRY AFTER
POLICE IN BELIZE WANTED TO
QUESTION HIM IN HIS NEIGHBOR'S
MURDER.
>>> AND FISCAL CLIFF FEARS BEING
FELT ON WALL STREET.
THE DOW DROPPING 74 POINTS,
DESPITE THE RELEASE OF UPBEAT
ECONOMIC DATA.
>>> NOW, MANY MERCHANTS ARE
SWEATING OUT THESE LAST TWO
WEEKS UNTIL CHRISTMAS TO SEE IF
WEAK CONSUMER CONFIDENT HURTS
THEIR BOTTOM LINES, BUT IN
WASHINGTON, SOME COMMUNITY
LEADERS ARE POINTING TO A LOCAL
MARKETING INITIATIVE AS PROOF
THAT EVEN TOUGH ECONOMIES CAN BE
BEATEN.
TOM FOREMAN HAS TONIGHT'S
"AMERICAN JOURNEY."
>> THIS IS THE NORMAL WAY TO DO
BUSINESS.
>> Reporter: FAR FROM THE MALLS
IN THE MIDDLE OF DOWNTOWN D.C.,
THE HOLIDAY MARKET IS ONCE AGAIN
SWINGING TO LIFE WITH OLD WORLD
CHARM.
FOR EIGHT YEARS NOW, EVEN
THROUGH THE DARKEST DAYS OF THE
RECESSION, IT HAS BEEN A
STEADILY GROWING STORY OF
SUCCESS FOR HUNDREDS OF ARTISANS
AND CRAFT DEALERS SELLING
PRODUCTS FROM AROUND THE GLOBE.
MICHAEL HELPS RUN THE MARKET
WHICH WAS STARTED IN PART IT
DRAW MORE SHOPPERS TO THE AREA.
HOW MANY PEOPLE COME THROUGH
HERE?
WE'RE GETTING ABOUT 10,000
PEOPLE A DAY.
AND THIS PAST SATURDAY, WE WERE
SO CROWDED, I THINK THE NUMBER
MIGHT HAVE BEEN DOUBLE.
>> Reporter: FOR SMALL VENDORS,
THOSE CROWDS ARE PURE GOLD.
ASHLEY ROBERTSON IS A SOAP MAKER
FROM VIRGINIA WHOSE INVENTORY
HAS ALREADY ALMOST SOLD OUT.
>> HOW MUCH?
OH, MY GOSH, WE BROUGHT A BUS
AND WE ALMOST EMPTIED IT.
A BUS FULL OF STUFF, YEAH.
>> Reporter: RON CAME ALL THE
WAY FROM TEXAS TO OFFER BUFFALO
HATS, AND YOU SOLD HOW MANY?
>> ABOUT 200.
>> Reporter: IN WHAT PERIOD OF
TIME?
>> A WEEK.
>> Reporter: A WEEK?
>> YEAH.
IF YOU WALK UP AND DOWN THE
STREET HERE, YOU WILL SEE A
BUNCH OF THEM HERE IN THE NEXT
COUPLE OF HOURS.
>> Reporter: THE MARKET HAS ALSO
PROVEN A GREAT PLACE FOR VENDORS
TO TEST PRODUCTS BEFORE OPENING
TRADITIONAL BRICK-AND-MORTAR
STORES.
>> WITHOUT THE BURDEN OF
JUMPING INTO THE DEEP END OF THE
POOL WITH RENT AND INSURANCE AND
ALL OF THE HEAVY DUTY INVESTMENT
THAT YOU HAVE TO DO.
BUT ONCE YOU KNOW YOU'RE GOING
TO BE SUCCESSFUL, NOW CAN YOU GO
FORWARD.
>> Reporter: AND YOU HAVE THAT
HAPPEN HERE A LOT?
>> WE HAVE.
WE HAVE.
>> Reporter: STALLS ARE NOW SO
PRIZED AND SPACE SO LIMITED,
THERE IS SIMPLY NOT ENOUGH ROOM
FOR ALL THE VENDORS WHO WANT TO
BE HERE.
BUT FOR THOSE WHO ARE CHOSEN
EACH YEAR FOR A FEW LUCKY
WEEKS --
>> LET ME JUST PUT IT ON THERE.
>> Reporter: -- THE HOLIDAYS ARE
TRULY CAUSE FOR CELEBRATION.
>> OH, GREAT, THANK YOU.
>> Reporter: TOM FOREMAN, CNN,
WASHINGTON.
>> AND IT IS GOOD TO SEE.
ANDERSON WILL BE RIGHT BACK WITH
THE RIDICULIST.
w?
>>> TIME FOR "THE RIDICULIST."
TONIGHT WE'RE ADDING SOMETHING
I'M CALLING THE CNBC DANGER
ZONE.
NO, THAT'S NOT THE NAME OF A NEW
SHOW WHERE MARIA BARTIROMO AND
WARREN BUFFETT GO ROCK CLIMBING.
THOUGH, FRANKLY, I THINK IT
SHOULD BE.
THE CNBC DANGER ZONE IS WHAT
HAPPENED WHEN NOTED ECONOMIST
GLENN HUBBARD SAT DOWN FOR AN
INTERVIEW WITH CNBC'S MELISSA
LEE.
EVERYTHING WAS GOING FINE UNTIL
I CAN ONLY ASSUME THE NBC
PEACOCK GOT A LITTLE FIESTY OFF
CAMERA.
>> THEY EITHER HAVE TO RAISE
TAXES OR CUT SOME OTHER
SPENDING.
THAT FORCES THE CONGRESS TO
THINK ABOUT THE MIX BETWEEN
TAXES, SPENDING OUTSIDE OF THE
ENTITLEMENTS AND SPENDING ON THE
ENTITLEMENTS.
THAT'S JUST NOT SOMETHING THAT
OUR FRAMERS THOUGHT ABOUT
BECAUSE WE DIDN'T HAVE A WELFARE
STATE IN THOSE DAYS.
>> FIRST OF ALL, I LOVE HOW HE
CONTINUED ON, MAKING HIS POINTS.
THAT, ALI VELSHI, IS WHAT YOU
CALL A PRO.
SECOND OF ALL, YOU WILL NOT SEE
CNN GUESTS RUNNING INTO THAT
PROBLEM.
THAT'S RIGHT, WE DO NOT WASTE
OUR MONEY ON FANCY, DANGEROUS
SIGNS FOR OUR REMOTE LOCATIONS.
ALL DAVID GERGEN NEEDS IS SOME
LIP GLOSS AND A LAVA LAMP AND
HE'S GOOD TO GO.
THAT BEING SAID, CNN ANCHORS
HAVE ACTUALLY ENCOUNTERED SOME
ONSET MISHAPS, AND IT TURNS OUT
IT IS A GLOBAL PROBLEM.
[ SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE ]
>> LOOSELY TRANSLATED, THAT WAS
DAMN YOU, WOLF BLITZER.
OF COURSE THERE ARE A LOT OF
POTENTIAL HAZARDS FOR FOLKS ON
TV.
SOMETIMES A SIGN FALLS,
SOMETIMES THE LIGHTS FALL AND
SOMETIMES, AS OUR FRIEND FROM
WSMV REMINDS US, EVEN THE
REPORTER FALLS.
>> Reporter: AND LOOK, THEY'RE
BIG.
THIS ONE IS ABOUT 12 POUNDS, BUT
THEY CAN GROW TO --
[ LAUGHING ]
>> I'M TELLING YOU, NEVER WORK
WITH ANIMALS OR FISH.
IT IS ALL FUN AND GAMES UNTIL
YOU HAVE TO PRY A LARGE-MOUTHED
BASS OFF GARY TUCHMAN'S NECK.
BUT BACK TO THAT CNBC INCIDENT.
THE GUEST WAS A PRO, THE ANCHOR
WAS A PRO.
NO HARM DONE.
I JUST WANT TO POINT OUT THAT
CNBC STILL HAS A LONG WAY TO GO
IF IT REALLY WANTS TO MAKE
HISTORY IN THE FINANCIAL NEWS
BLOOPER DEPARTMENT.
>> AT NO POINT WERE YOU RUNNING
A GYM?
>> NO, NO.
RUNNING A GYM?