>>> HELLO.
I'M WOLF BLITZER.
I'M COMING TO YOU WITH LIVE
SPECIAL COVERAGE FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, THE SCENE OF THE
HORRIFIC ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
MASSACRE.
WE WANT TO WELCOME BACK OUR
VIEWERS IN THE UNITED STATES AND
AROUND THE WORLD.
WE'RE LEARNING NEW INFORMATION
ABOUT THIS MASS KILLING HERE IN
CONNECTICUT AND WE'RE LEARNING
NEW INFORMATION ABOUT THE PEOPLE
WHO WERE KILLED.
26 PEOPLE SHOT INSIDE THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
20 OF THEM CHILDREN.
AT A NEWS CONFERENCE JUST A
LITTLE WHILE AGO HERE IN
NEWTOWN, THE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE SAID THAT ALL OF THE
VICTIMS NOW HAVE BEEN
IDENTIFIED.
THEY WILL BE RELEASED -- THEY
WILL BE RELEASING THE NAME
SHORTLY.
WE'RE TOLD TO BE STANDING BY.
ALL OF THE BODIES HAVE BEEN
REMOVED AND THEY'VE BEEN TAKEN
TO THE MEDICAL EXAMINER'S
OFFICE.
CRIME SCENE INVESTIGATORS ARE
WORKING AROUND THE CLOCK.
HERE'S HOW THEY ARE TRYING TO
DEAL WITH WHAT'S GOING ON.
INVESTIGATORS SAY -- THEY SPOKE
OUT A FEW MOMENTS AGO.
>> WE STILL HAVE MAJOR CRIME
DETECTIVES AND NEWTOWN
DETECTIVES WORKING AT THE SCENE
AT THE SCHOOL.
THAT IS NOT COMPLETED.
THAT PROBABLY WILL NOT BE
COMPLETED FOR AT LEAST ANOTHER
DAY TO A DAY AND A HALF.
I'M PUTTING A TIMELINE ON IT AND
IT COULD TAKE LONGER.
EVERYTHING WE NEED TO DO TO
LITERALLY PEAL BACK THE ONION
LAYER BY LAY AND EXAMINE EVERY
CREVICE AND CRACK OF THAT
FACILITY.
THAT DOES NOT EXCLUDE THE
OUTSIDE OF THE BUILDING.
IT'S ALSO PART OF THE CRIME
SCENE, EVERY VEHICLE IN THAT
LOT.
IT'S GOING TO BE A PAINSTAKING
PROCESS.
ONCE WE HAVE A TENTATIVE
IDENTIFICATION ON THE SUSPECT,
WE BEGIN DOING A GREAT DEAL OF
WORK, AGAIN, PEELING BACK THE
ONION.
INCLUDING AND NOT LIMITING TO
RELATIVES, FRIENDS, CO-WORKERS,
FORMER STUDENTS, LOCATION OF
RESIDENCE.
ALL OF THOSE PEOPLE HAD TO BE
INTERVIEWED AND ALL OF THOSE
AREAS HAD TO BE EXAMINED, HENCE
THAT CAUSED THE SECONDARY CRIME
SCENE WHICH WAS A SOLE FEMALE
DECEASED.
>> THE WOMAN THAT VANCE WAS
REFERRING TO, NANCY LANZA, THE
MOTHER OF THE SHOOTER IDENTIFIED
AS 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA.
POLICE HAVE DESCRIBED WHAT THEY
CALL GOOD EVIDENCE BUT THEY ARE
NOT RELEASING THAT INFORMATION,
AT LEAST NOT YET.
SCHOOL EMPLOYEES WHO WERE INSIDE
THE SCHOOL DURING THE SHOOTING
ARE STARTING TO COME FORWARD TO
DESCRIBE THEIR HARROWING ORDEAL.
EARLIER THIS MORNING THE SCHOOL
LIBRARIAN WHO WORKED AT THE
SCHOOL TALKED ABOUT THE SCHOOL'S
PRINCIPAL, ONE OF THE VICTIMS IN
THIS TRAGEDY.
>> SHE WASN'T IN HER OFFICE.
SHE WAS IN A MEETING.
HE WENT THROUGH THE FRONT DOOR,
IF YOU GO IN THE FRONT DOOR THE
OFFICE IS IN FRONT OF YOU.
HE WENT BY THE FIRST-CLASS ROOM
AND THE NEXT TWO CLASSROOMS IS
WHERE THE SHOOTINGS TOOK PLACE.
SHE WAS IN A MEETING, I HEARD,
ACROSS THE HALLWAY AND SHE MUST
HAVE COME OUT AND CONFRONTED HIM
ON HIS WAY DOWN THE HALLWAY.
THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST, MARY
SHERLACH WAS KILLED.
>> WHAT CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT
THE REACTION OF SOME OF THE
TEACHERS AND PROTECTING THEIR
CHILDREN?
>> I THINK EVERYBODY DOES WHAT
THEY HAVE TO DO WHEN THEY ARE
CONFRONTED WITH A SITUATION LIKE
THAT AND EVERYBODY -- YOU KNOW,
WE PRACTICE IT AND THEY KNEW
WHAT TO DO AND YOU JUST -- YOU
THINK ABOUT PROTECTING THE KIDS
AND JUST DOING THE RIGHT THING.
>> HOW HAVE YOU PRACTICED THIS?
>> WE HAVE LOCKDOWN DRILLS.
I DON'T REMEMBER HOW MANY BUT
YOU HAVE TO HAVE A CERTAIN
AMOUNT EVACUATION DRILLS AND
LOCKDOWN DRILLS.
SO THE KIDS KNOW THE ROUTINE AND
EVERYONE HAS A SPOT IN THE ROOM
THAT THEY ARE TO GO TO.
>> CAN YOU DESCRIBE THAT SPOT?
>> IN THE LIBRARY IT'S A
BOOKCASE UP AGAINST THE WALL.
WE HAD TO MOVE OUT OF THE SPOT
BECAUSE ONE OF OUR DOORS WAS NOT
LOCKED.
WE WENT INTO THE BACK STORAGE
ROOM.
>> HOW CLOSE WERE YOU?
>> WE WERE THIS CLOSE TOGETHER.
THERE WAS CRAYONS AND PAPER IN
THE STORAGE ROOM IN THE BACK AND
WE TORE SOME UP AND GAVE THEM
CLIP BOARDS AND HAD THEM COLOR.
>> WHO WAS WITH YOU?
WERE YOU ALONE?
>> THERE WERE THREE AIDES WITH
US.
>> YOU DIDN'T KNOW AT THAT
POINT?
>> WE KNEW BECAUSE I CALLED THE
OFFICE AND SHE TOLD ME THERE WAS
A SHOOTER.
>> A LOT TO LEARN.
WE THINK THE NAMES OF THE
VICTIMS OF THIS HORRIFIC ATTACK,
ONCE AGAIN, 20 SCHOOL CHILDREN,
AGES BETWEEN 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY DIED IN THIS RAMPAGE.
SIX ADULTS WERE AMONG THOSE
SHOTS INSIDE THE SCHOOL
INCLUDING THE SCHOOL PRINCIPAL
AND SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST.
NICK VALENCIA IS JOINING US WITH
MORE ABOUT WHAT IS GOING ON.
WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THESE
VICTIMS, AREN'T WE, NICK?
>> WE ARE.
TERRIBLE, TRAGIC STORIES COMING
OUT OF NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE'VE WAITED ALL MORNING TO GET
THIS COMPLETE LIST OF THE
VICTIMS.
SO FAR LOCAL POLICE HAS NOT
RELEASED THE NAMES BUT CNN HAS
BEEN ABLE TO INDEPENDENTLY
CONFIRM TWO OF THOSE NAMES.
ONE BEING DAWN HOCHSPRUNG.
SHE WAS THE PRINCIPAL.
SHE WAS DESCRIBED AS SOMEBODY
THAT YOU WOULD WANT EDUCATING
YOUR CHILDREN, WOLF.
SHE'S THE TEACHER'S TEACHER.
SHE WAS A VERY INVOLVED EDUCATOR
WITH MEMORABLE ENTHUSIASM.
AS YOU SEE FROM THAT PHOTO ON
YOUR SCREEN, SOMEONE WITH A
BEAUTIFUL SMILE.
SHE CREATED AN ENVIRONMENT THAT
MADE PEOPLE FEEL ACCEPTED AND
IMPORTANT.
SHE HAD BEEN WORKING HER WAY UP
THROUGH THE CONNECTICUT SCHOOL
SYSTEM AND HAD SPENT SOME TIME
IN ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS, MIDDLE
SCHOOLS, AND HIGH SCHOOLS AND
HAD TAKEN THAT JOB THERE AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL TWO
YEARS AGO.
NOT JUST A TEACHER, SOMEBODY
VERY PASSIONATE ABOUT HER OWN
EDUCATION.
SHE RECENTLY ENROLLED IN A PH.D.
PROGRAM.
SHE LEAVES BEHIND A HUSBAND, TWO
DAUGHTERS AND THREE
STEPDAUGHTERS AS WELL.
MARY SHERLACH, THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST, SHE WAS ALSO A
VICTIM THERE OF THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
WE HEARD THE LIBRARIAN TALK
ABOUT A MEETING TAKING PLACE
BETWEEN SOME OF THE
ADMINISTRATORS.
THEY HEARD THIS POP, POP, POP IN
THE HALLWAY.
THEY WENT TO INVESTIGATE AND AT
WHICH POINT WERE CONFRONTED
POSSIBLY BY THE GUNMAN AND THEY
NEVER RETURNED.
BUT MARY SHERLACH WAS DESCRIBED
BY PEOPLE THAT KNEW HER AS PART
OF THE CRISIS INTERVENTION TEAM.
SO THIS A PERSON, WOLF, THAT
PEOPLE WOULD BE GOING TO AND
GRIEVING WITH AT A TIME LIKE
THIS AND SHE'S NO LONGER AROUND
FOR PEOPLE TO TALK TO.
SHE'S NOT WITH US ANYMORE.
SHE WAS AN EXPERT IN
PSYCHOLOGIST.
SHE GOT HER MASTER'S FROM
SOUTHERN CONNECTICUT UNIVERSITY
AND SPENT A LOT OF TIME WORKING
IN THE COMMUNITY AND DID A LOT
OF WORK WITH DISABLED ADULTS.
THOSE ARE JUST TWO OF THE NAMES
OF THE 26 VICTIMS THAT FELL
VICTIM TO THE SHOOTER IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WOLF?
>> TWO NAMES AND THEY ARE GOING
TO BE RELEASING THE REST OF THE
NAMES.
WE'RE STANDING BY FOR ANOTHER
NEWS CONFERENCE.
WE THINK THAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN
FAIRLY SOON.
WITH MORE QUESTIONS THAN ANSWERS
RIGHT NOW, AT LEAST ON THIS
MORNING ABOUT THE POSSIBLE
MOTIVES OF THIS 20-YEAR-OLD
SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA, WE'RE
CONTINUING TO TRY TO GET
INFORMATION ON WHAT HAPPENED.
POLICE SAY HE KILLED HIS MOTHER
BEFORE THE RAMPAGE AT THE SCHOOL
WHERE HE THEN EVENTUALLY TOOK
HIS OWN LIFE.
CNN'S MARY SNOW IS JOINING US
FROM OUTSIDE THE LANZA HOME IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WHAT DID WE LEARN ABOUT ADAM
LANZA AND HIS POSSIBLE MOTIVE?
>> Reporter: WOLF, YOU KNOW,
SHORTLY AFTER YESTERDAY'S
HORRIFIC MASSACRE, POLICE AND
S.W.A.T. TEAMS DESCENDED ON THE
LANZA HOME WHERE IT IS BELIEVED
THAT ADAM LANZA LIVED WITH HIS
MOTHER.
AND WHAT POLICE NOW ARE SAYING
IN TERM OF A POTENTIAL MOTIVE,
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE OF THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE SAID
THAT INVESTIGATORS ARE
RECOVERING WHAT HE DESCRIBED AS,
IN HIS WORDS, AS GOOD EVIDENCE
TO POSSIBLY FILL IN THE BLANKS
OF WHY OR HOW THIS COULD HAVE
OCCURRED.
AND HE GAVE THAT ANSWER WHEN
ASKED WHETHER OR NOT THERE WERE
ANY E-MAILS OR ANY WRITINGS THAT
WOULD GIVE ANY CLUES ABOUT A POE
TE
POTENTIAL MOTIVE.
WE HAVE NEW INFORMATION ABOUT
FROM SUSAN CANDIOTTI.
SHE IS QUOTING A LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIAL WHO SAID THAT HE HAD
ACCESS TO MORE GUNS THAN THE
THREE GUNS RECOVERED.
SHE'S QUOTING A SOURCE THAT
POLICE RECOVERED THREE
ADDITIONAL GUNS.
AND THIS WAS ELSEWHERE, NOT AT
THE SCENE OF THE SHOOTING.
A .45 REVOLVER HAND REPEATING
AND CNN HAS BEEN REPORTING THAT
POLICE DID RECOVER THREE
WEAPONS, TWO HANDGUNS AND A
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE AND THAT
THOSE GUNS HAD BEEN PURCHASED BY
NANCY LANZA.
THERE IS NOT MUCH WE KNOW ABOUT
WE SPOKE TO A NEIGHBOR A SHORT
TIME AGO.
SHE TOLD US THAT THERE WAS
NOTHING OUT OF THE ORDINARY
ABOUT NANCY LANZA.
>> SHE WAS LIKE A NORMAL ANYBODY
ELSE IN THIS NEIGHBORHOOD.
YOU KNOW, DECORATE THE HOUSE AND
THE HOUSE WAS ALWAYS, YOU KNOW,
PRISTINE.
SHE WAS JUST LIKE ANY OTHER
HOUSEWIFE.
>> Reporter: AND THAT NEIGHBOR
WAS SAYING THAT AS FAR AS SHE
KNEW THAT NANCY LANZA FROM THE
TIME THAT SHE KNEW HER, SHE WAS
A STAY-AT-HOME MOM AND SAW HER A
COUPLE OF MONTHS AGO.
THE FAMILY WAS DESCRIBED AS NOT
BEING VERY SOCIAL, BEING VERY
QUIET.
WOLF?
>> MARY, THANKS VERY MUCH.
SANJAY GUPTA IS HERE, OUR CHIEF
MEDICAL CORRESPONDENT.
YOU JUST CAME BACK FROM THE
CRISIS CENTER.
TELL US WHAT YOU SAW AND WHAT
WAS GOING ON.
>> IT WAS UNCLEAR TO ME HOW MANY
PEOPLE WOULD BE USING THE CENTER
AND I CAN TELL YOU THAT IT'S AT
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL A MILE FROM
HERE.
IT'S SET UP BY DANBURY HOSPITAL,
THE HOSPITAL THAT TREATED THE
FEW THAT WERE WOUNDED YESTERDAY.
THERE WERE PROBABLY ABOUT 100
CARS IN THE PARKING LOT.
OBVIOUSLY OUT OF RESPECT FOR
PRIVACY WE DID NOT FILM THEM.
FAMILIES COMING IN, SMALL
CHILDREN, SOME SINGLE MOMS AND
DADS AND ENTIRE FAMILIES AS WELL
AND THEY ARE STAYING FOR A LONG
TIME.
THIS ISN'T ONE OF THOSE THINGS
WHERE PEOPLE ARE COMING IN AND
OUT CONSTANTLY.
THEY WERE GOING IN AND STAYING
IN FOR QUITE A WHILE.
THE WHOLE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
DEDICATED TO THIS TODAY FOR 12
HOURS.
IN ADDITION, YALE NEW HAVEN
WHICH HAS A NATIONALLY
RENOWNED --
>> YALE UNIVERSITY?
>> YALE UNIVERSITY.
THEY ARE NOT TOO FAR FROM HERE.
THEY HAVE A PHONE LINE SET UP
AND PEOPLE HAVE BEEN CALLING IN
NOT ONLY FROM THIS AREA BUT FROM
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
THIS IS SOMETHING THAT WE'RE
HEARING PEOPLE FROM ALL OVER THE
COUNTRY HAVE BEEN AFFECTED BY
AND USING SOME OF THESE
RESOURCES.
>> SO THEY ARE BRINGING IN A
PSYCHOLOGIST AND PSYCHIATRIST
AND OTHER PROFESSIONALS AS WELL?
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
PARTICULARLY CHILD COUNSELORS,
THE PEOPLE WHO SPECIALIZE IN
DEALING WITH CHILDREN.
THEY HAVE PSYCHOLOGISTS AND
PSYCHIATRISTS, OBVIOUSLY PEOPLE
WHO ARE MEDICAL DOCTORS.
THK THEY CAN PRESCRIBE
MEDICATIONS.
AGAIN, PEOPLE ARE CLEARLY USING
THESE RESOURCES.
THEY DON'T WANT TO TALK,
OBVIOUSLY, IN THE PARKING LOT
ABOUT IT, GOING IN QUITE
PRIVATELY.
BUT YOU CAN TELL THAT THERE'S A
HUGE DEMAND, WOLF.
>> BECAUSE IF YOU'RE A MOM,
YOU'RE A DAD AND YOU'VE SEEN
WHAT'S GOING ON, FORTUNATELY
LET'S SAY YOUR KIDS ARE OKAY BUT
YOU'RE STILL IN A STATE OF
SHOCK, WHAT KIND OF MEDICAL
TREATMENT -- THERE ARE PROBABLY
SOME PRESCRIPTIONS, SOME DRUGS
THAT YOU CAN GIVE, BUT WHAT DO
YOU DO?
>> YOU KNOW, ONE OF THE THINGS
THAT I -- AND YOU AND I HAVE
COVERED A LOT OF THESE.
BUT FOR PARENTS REALLY CHECKING
THEIR OWN FEELINGS FIRST.
MAKING SURE THEY HAVE THEIR OWN
FEELINGS IN CONTROL.
IT'S BEEN HARD FOR ME AND I'M
SURE FOR YOU AS WELL TO MAKE
SURE THAT YOU HAVE SOME CONTROL
OF YOUR FEELINGS AND THEN BEING
AS TRANSPARENT AS POSSIBLE ABOUT
THIS.
ONE OF THE TECHNIQUES THAT I
THINK REALLY SEEMS TO MAKE A
DIFFERENCE AND I KEEP HEARING
THIS FROM THE EXPERTS IN THIS
FIELD IS LET THE CHILD IN THIS
CASE DO THE TALKING FIRST.
REALLY GET AN IDEA OF HOW MUCH
THEY KNOW AND THEN SLOWLY FILL
IN DETAILS BUT NOT TOO
PHOTOGRAPH SPECIFGRAPHIC
DETAILS.
IT SOUNDS ALMOST TOO SIMPLE IN A
SITUATION LIKE THIS, TOO SMALL,
BUT IT CAN MAKE A BIG
DIFFERENCE.
IT'S AROUND THE HOLIDAYS.
PEOPLE MAY HAVE HOLIDAY
ACTIVITIES, SOCCER PRACTICE,
THINGS LIKE THAT.
GETTING BACK INTO THAT GROOVE.
WHAT THEY FIND IS IF YOU CAN
ESTABLISH THAT SOONER RATHER
THAN LATER, YOU'RE MUCH MORE
LIKELY TO REALLY MITIGATE SOME
OF THESE SYMPTOMS.
I WAS LOOKING AT SOME OF THE
DATA, FOR EXAMPLE, FROM VIRGINIA
TECH.
EVEN ABOUT THREE TO FOUR MONTHS
AFTERWARDS, ABOUT 15% OF PEOPLE
STILL HAD SIGNIFICANT PTSD.
IF PEOPLE ACTUALLY SAW SOME OF
THE VIOLENCE, IT WENT UP TO AS
HIGH AS 77%.
YOU TYPICALLY THINK OF PTSD
SOMETHING THAT YOU SEE IN ADULTS
BUT YOU CLEARLY SEE IT IN
CHILDREN AS WELL AND WE'RE
GETTING MORE AND MORE EVIDENCE
OF THAT ALL THE TIME.
>> WOULD IT BE SMART FOR THESE
LITTLE KIDS, THERE ARE UNDER 600
KIDS WHO WERE AT THIS ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, TO GO BACK TO THAT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND BEGIN THAT
ROUTINE OF GOING BACK TO SCHOOL?
>> YES.
BUT THE QUESTION IS AND I ASKED
THE SAME QUESTION, THE QUESTION
IS WHEN.
EVEN THE REED ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
SOME DISSTRANS FROM HERE, I
DON'T KNOW THE ANSWER TO THAT.
YES, ULTIMATELY THAT HAS TO BE
THE ANSWER BECAUSE YOU HAVE TO
RE-ESTABLISH THAT ROUTINE AND
YOU ALSO HAVE TO MAKE IT CLEAR
THAT WHILE SOMETHING TERRIBLE
HAPPENED HERE AND VERY
FRIGHTENING, THIS CAN STILL BE A
PLACE THAT CAN BE SAFE FOR THEM.
>> I'M GLAD THEY ARE BRINGING IN
A LOT OF PROFESSIONALS WITH A
LOT OF EXPERIENCE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU CAN SAY.
I GUESS THE MEDICAL PROFESSIONAL
IS ONE THING, CLERGY CAN BE VERY
HELPFUL, TOO.
>> AND THE COMMUNITY AS A WHOLE.
IT'S INTERESTING, ONE THING THAT
ALWAYS COMES UP IS THAT
EVERYBODY SUFFERS HERE SOMEWHAT.
AND I THINK PEOPLE TEND TO FEEL
VERY ISOLATED.
SO WHEN YOU HAVE THESE TYPES OF
FACILITIES, WHERE PEOPLE ARE
COMING TOGETHER, BESIDES THE
COUNSELORS, BESIDES THE
PSYCHOLOGISTS, PSYCHIATRISTS,
EVEN THE CLERGY AND SEEING YOUR
FELLOW COMMUNITY MEMBERS GOING
THROUGH THE SAME THING THAT
YOU'RE GOING THROUGH, THAT'S
PART OF THE PURPOSE OF CREATING
A CENTRAL PLACE WHERE PEOPLE CAN
DO THIS.
BECAUSE THAT FEELING OF
ISOLATION I THINK CAN BE QUITE
TROUBLESOME.
>> SANJAY, THANK YOU FOR THAT
REPORT.
SANJAY IS GOING TO BE WITH US
OBVIOUSLY THROUGHOUT ALL OF OUR
COVERAGE TODAY, TOMORROW, WE'RE
HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
THIS STORY HAS RESONATED TO SO
MANY PEOPLE AROUND THE WORLD.
WE'RE ALSO WATCHING THE
INVESTIGATION AS IT IS UNFOLDING
AND THERE ARE A LOT OF ISSUES AT
STAKE IN THIS INVESTIGATION.
LOU PALUMBO IS JOINING US.
HE KNOWS HOW THESE
INVESTIGATIONS UNFOLD.
WATCH US HOW -- IF YOU WERE
INVOLVED IN THIS VINVESTIGATION
WHAT'S THE SINGLE MOST IMPORTANT
THING THAT YOU WOULD BE DOING
RIGHT NOW?
>> CERTAINLY TRYING TO ESTABLISH
WHETHER OR NOT THIS GENTLEMAN
HAD ANYONE ACT IN CONCERT WITH
HIM AND ATTEMPTING TO DETERMINE
SPECIFICALLY HOW HE WAS ABLE TO
GAIN ACCESS TO THE SCHOOL.
AND WE DO HAVE SOME INFORMATION
REGARDING THE ACCESS ISSUE.
BUT THE INVESTIGATION THAT THEY
ARE CONDUCTING IS GOING TO BE
ONGOING FOR QUITE SOME TIME.
>> DAYS, WEEKS, MONTHS?
HOW LONG DOES AN INVESTIGATION
LIKE THIS ROUTINELY AND THIS IS
FAR FROM ROUTINE, GO ON?
>> WELL, EVERY INVESTIGATION
STANDS ON IT IS OWN MERIT AND
THE SEVERITY AND NATURE OF THE
INCIDENT, IT COULD TAKE A COUPLE
OF DAYS.
I KNOW THAT THE POLICE INITIALLY
ALLUDED TO WRAPPING UP IN THE
NEXT DAY OR SO.
I WOULD HAVE TO SAY THAT THEY
ARE PROBABLY ON POINT BUT THE
INVESTIGATION ISN'T JUST
FOCUSING ON THIS CLASSROOM, AS
THEY ALREADY HE CEXPLAINED.
IT'S ALSO FOCUSED ON THE
RESIDENCE OF THE MOTHER AND THIS
SHOOTER.
SO THIS INVESTIGATION HAS SOME
TIME.
THERE'S A LOT OF DURATION THAT
THEY HAVE TO COMPILE, THINGS
LIKE DISTANCE FROM THE VICTIMS,
ANGLES, NUMBER OF SHOTS FIRED,
RECOVERY OF THE CASINGS, TRYING
TO FIND THE BULLETS IN WALLS.
TO RETRIEVE THEM AND CONCLUDE
BALLASTICALLY THAT THEY CAME
FROM A WEAPON.
I THINK THEY HAVE A LOT OF WORK
TO DO YET.
THEY ARE STILL GOING TO GO
OUT -- EVEN THOUGH THEY REALIZE
THAT HIS MOM LEGALLY ACQUIRED
THE WEAPONS, THEY ARE GOING TO
FIND OUT WHERE SHE ACQUIRED THEM
AS WELL AS HOW SHE WAS ABLE TO
GET THE WEAPONS FROM THE HOUSE
IN WHICH HE RESIDED.
WE ARE ALL WORKING FROM THE
PREMISE THAT SHE HADN'T PROPERLY
SECURED THEM.
SHE MAY HAVE ESPECIALLY WITH THE
FACT THAT HE HAD A PERSONALITY
DISORDER.
THE INVESTIGATION WILL FURTHER
TELL US IF HE BEAT HER UP,
FORCING HER TO SURRENDER THESE
WEAPONS.
THERE'S A LOT OF INFORMATION
THAT HAS TO BE TIED TOGETHER
YET.
>> DEBRA FREYRICK HAS A QUESTION
FOR YOU.
>> WHY DO YOU THINK THAT NANCY
LANZA WOULD NEED A GUN IN THAT
TIGHT-KNIT, MIDDLE-INCOME OF A
FLEW WENT COMMUNITY?
WHY THE NEED FOR A GUN?
>> WELL, QUITE CANDIDLY, ALL
SHE'D HAVE TO DO IS WATCH THE
NEWS WHERE WE HAVE A CONCERN
ABOUT TAKING YOUR CHILD TO THE
MOVIE THEATER OR SHOPPING MALL
OR SENDING THEM TO A SCHOOL OR
UNIVERSITY.
ANY ONE OF THESE DENOMINATORS
COULD PROMPT A PERSON TO BELIEVE
THAT THEY NEED A TOOL OF THIS
TYPE.
THE QUESTION IS, WHY DID SHE
HAVE A SIG SAUER P 229 OR --
THERE'S A NUMBER OF
CONFIGURATIONS OR A GLOCK
PISTOL.
THEY ARE BOTH HIGH-POWERED
SEMIAUTOMATIC AND IN A GLOCK 17,
BLOCK 19 OR BLOCK 26.
AND THEN WE'RE LOOKING AT THE M4
CARBINE OF THE BUSHMASTER.
THIS IS ALL CONJECTURE.
MAYBE SHE FELT LIKE SHE NEEDED
TO HAVE TOOLS LIKE THIS TO
PROTECT HER FAMILY.
THIS IS ALL CONJECTURE.
IT'S DIFFICULT TO UNDERSTAND WHY
YOU WOULD HAVE MULTIPLE WEAPONS
OF THESE TYPES.
YOU HAVE TO REMEMBER SOMETHING
OF THESE WEAPONS.
THESE ARE WEAPONS THAT ARE
DESIGNED TO STAGE ASSAULT OR
RESPOND TO AN ASSAULT.
THAT'S THEIR ONLY PURPOSE BLOCK
17 OR OTHER GLOCKS ARE NOT
HUNTING VESSELS.
IT'S DESIGNED AS AN OFFENSIVE OR
DEFENSIVE WEAPON.
>> THAT'S A BIG QUESTION.
CLEARLY A LOT OF POLICE OFFICERS
LOOKING INTO WHY SHE HAD THOSE
TYPES OF WEAPONS, WHETHER THERE
WAS A REASON FOR THAT.
WE TALKED ABOUT PSYCHOLOGICAL
TESTING HOW PEOPLE CAN BUY A GUN
WITHOUT PSYCHOLOGICAL TESTING
BUT THIS TAKES US TO ANOTHER
LEVEL BECAUSE IF SOMEBODY IS
GOING TO FORCE POSSESSION OF A
GUN, THAT'S SOMETHING TOTALLY
DIFFERENT.
WOLF?
>> LOU PALUMBO, THANK YOU AS
WELL.
>> COLUMBINE RIGHT NOW HERE AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
WITH EVERY SCHOOL SHOOTING,
EVERY PARENT THINKS, IT COULD
HAVE BEEN MY CHILD, GOD FORBID.
WHAT CAN WE DO TO SAVE
CHILDREN'S LIVES DOWN THE ROAD?
MUCH MORE OF OUR SPECIAL
COVERAGE RIGHT AFTER THIS.
>>> WE HAVE JUST BEEN TOLD THAT
THE SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON HAS SUFFERED A
CONCUSSION.
A STATEMENT RELEASED BY THE
STATE DEPARTMENT, I'LL JUST READ
IT TO YOU.
HERE IT IS.
AND OUR FOREIGN AFFAIRS
SECRETARY RELEASING THIS
STATEMENT.
WHILE SUFFERING FROM A STOP MASS
VIRUS, SECRETARY CLINTON BECAME
DEHYDRATED AND FAINTED
SUSTAINING A CONCUSSION.
SHE HAS BEEN RECOVERING AT HOME
AND WILL CONTINUE TO BE
MONITORED REGULARLY BY HER
DOCTORS.
SHE WILL CONTINUE TO WORK FROM
HOME NEXT WEEK STAYING IN
REGULAR CONTACT WITH OFFICIALS.
SHE'S LOOKING FORWARD TO BEING
BACK IN OFFICE SOON.
DR. SANJAY GUPTA, A NEUROSURGEON
HIMSELF, HE'S HERE.
SANJAY, SHE'S OBVIOUSLY NOT
FEELING WELL.
SHE MUST HAVE FALLEN, I ASSUME,
HIT HER HEAD, AND SUFFERS A
CONCUSSION?
>> YEAH.
THE FIRST THING -- THE FAINTING
PRECEDED THE CONCUSSION.
ONE OF THE MOST COMMON THINGS IS
YOU HAVE SOMEBODY WHO BECOMES
DEHYDRATED.
THAT'S ONE OF THE TOP REASONS
THAT WOULD COME TO MIND WHEN
SOMEBODY ELSE THINKS OF A HEART
CONDITION BUT THEY SAID SHE HAD
A STOMACH VIRUS.
TO FAINT TO THE POINT WHERE SHE
HIT HER HEAD, SHE DIDN'T BRACE
HERSELF SO SOUNDS LIKE SHE WAS
REALLY -- THE FAINTING SPELL WAS
QUITE SIGNIFICANT.
WITH A CONCUSSION ITSELF,
DOESN'T MEAN YOU NECESSARILY
LOSE CONSCIOUSNESS.
WHAT I READ INTO THE STATEMENT
SPECIFICALLY IS THAT THEY ARE
ALLOWING HER TO REST AT HOME.
IF THEY HAD SAID THAT SHE NEEDED
TO SPEND THE NIGHT IN THE
HOSPITAL OR SOMETHING ELSE, THAT
WOULD CLEARLY BE OF MORE
CONCERN.
BUT THIS SOUNDS LIKE SOMETHING
SHE SHOULD RECOVER FROM JUST
FINE.
IT'S OBVIOUSLY UNFORTUNATE AND
THE STOMACH VIRUS CAN MAKE
SOMEBODY DEHYDRATED TO THE POINT
WHERE YOU GET THAT FAINT, THAT'S
A CONCERN.
BEING THAT SHE IS AT HOME, SHE
PROBABLY DIDN'T NEED A C.A.T.
SCAN OR ANYTHING LIKE THAT.
>> AS A PRECAUTION, SECRETARY OF
STATE, SHE HAS A CONCUSSION, SHE
FANTS, YOU WOU
FAINTS, YOU WOULD THINK THAT
THEY WOULD WANT TO DO SOME
TESTING.
>> MAYBE THEY DID SOME TESTING,
BUT WHATEVER IT SHOWED IN THE
END DIDN'T WARRANT HER STAYING
IN THE HOSPITAL.
YOU WOULD WANT TO MAKE SURE
THERE WASN'T ANY BLOOD ON THE
BRAIN.
>> OUR REPORTER IS ON THE PHONE.
ELISE, YOU HAVE MORE
INFORMATION?
WAS SHE TAKEN TO THE HOSPITAL
FOR TESTING, CAT SCANS, OTHER
TESTS?
>> Reporter: SHE WAS OBVIOUSLY
TAKEN TO THE DOCTOR.
IN THE LAST WEEK, WE'VE BEEN
TALKING ABOUT THIS VIRUS THAT
SHE HAD.
AS YOU KNOW, SHE KEEPS THIS
PUNISHING SCHEDULE, WOLF.
THE LAST WEEK OR SO SHE'S REALLY
BEEN DOWN FOR THE COUNT.
YOU KNOW, EVEN THE STATE
DEPARTMENT HAD TO ACKNOWLEDGE
THAT THE STOMACH VIRUS WAS, YOU
KNOW, REALLY HIT SECRETARY
CLINTON HARD.
DEHYDRATION, FATIGUE, EVERYTHING
LIKE THAT.
THE FACT THAT SHE'S AT HOME, WE
KNOW SECRETARY CLINTON.
SHE NEVER REALLY STOPS WORKING.
SHE'LL CONTINUE TO MAKE CALLS
AND THE SUCH.
BUT THE FACT THAT SHE'S NOT IN
THE HOSPITAL RIGHT NOW SIGNIFIES
THAT HER DOCTORS THINK THAT
SHE'S OUT OF THE WOODS IN TERMS
OF ANY KIND OF SERIOUS INJURY.
>> I KNOW LAST WEEK SHE WAS
SUPPOSED TO GO ON AN IMPORTANT
TRIP TO MOROCCO.
SHE CANCELED THAT TRIP WHICH WAS
HIGHLY UNUSUAL, SENDING HER
DEPUTY TO MOROCCO FOR AN
IMPORTANT VISIT TO THAT NORTH
AFRICAN COUNTRY.
YOU'VE COVERED HER FOR THESE
LAST FOUR YEARS.
HOW EXTRAORDINARY IS IT THAT SHE
CANCELS A FOREIGN VISIT LIKE
THIS?
>> WOLF, I'VE BEEN COVERING
SECRETARY CLINTON SINCE SHE
STARTED.
I'VE DONE MANY TRAVELS WITH HER.
THE ONLY OTHER TIME SHE CANCELED
A TRIP IN THE LAST FOUR YEARS IS
WHEN HER MOTHER, WHO SHE IS VERY
CLOSE TO, FELL ILL AND DIED A
FEW DAYS LATER.
WHEN SHE DOESN'T FEEL GOOD, SHE
KEEPS A PUNISHING SCHEDULE.
SHE KEEPS A SCHEDULE THAT EVEN
SOME OF THE JOURNALISTS CAN'T
KEEP UP WITH HER.
SHE'S REALLY ALWAYS RUNNING,
ALWAYS WORKING, ALWAYS ON THE
JOB.
SO FOR HER, LAST WEEK, TO CANCEL
THIS TRIP WAS REALLY, REALLY
EXTRAORDINARY AND A LOT OF
PEOPLE STARTED TO TALK ABOUT,
WELL, IS THIS A MORE SERIOUS
CASE OF SOMETHING, SOME KIND OF
ILLNESS?
BUT, NO, WE JUST UNDERSTAND
THERE WERE SEVERAL OTHER PEOPLE
ON HER TRIP THAT ALSO FELL ILL.
NOT AS SICK AS SECRETARY CLINTON
BUT THEY SAID, LOOK, THIS IS A
REALLY BAD VIRUS, REALLY PUTS
YOU DOWN FOR THE COUNT, AND SHE
JUST NEEDED A LOT OF REST, A LOT
OF FLUIDS AND CARE.
>> YEAH.
IT'S ONE THING TO HAVE A VIRUS,
AS SANJAY IS HERE, AND IT'S
ANOTHER THING TO BE ACTUALLY
DEHYDRATED AND FAINT BUT THEN TO
HIT YOUR HEAD AND HAVE A
CONCUSSION, WALK US THROUGH.
THERE ARE CONCUSSION AND THERE
ARE CONCUSSIONS.
THERE ARE VARIOUS DEGREES OF
CONCUSSION.
>> RIGHT.
AS YOU KNOW, I WORKED FOR HER
WHEN SHE WAS FIRST LADY.
>> WHEN YOU WERE A WHITE HOUSE
FELLOW?
>> WHEN I WAS A WHITE HOUSE
FELLOW.
>> SHE WOULD BE SOLE NOOL HER
WORK, SHE WOULD HAVE TO BE
REMINDED TO EAT AND DRINK.
IT'S SOMETHING THAT ANY DOCTOR
WOULD CERTAINLY BE CONCERNED
ABOUT AND WHAT HAPPENS IS YOU
DROP YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE.
YOU'RE SIMPLY NOT GETTING ENOUGH
AND A MINOR FAINTING SPELL, IT
WAS SIGNIFICANT ENOUGH WHEN YOU
FALL AND BRACE WITH YOUR HAND,
THE INSTINCT IS TO PROTECT YOUR
HEAD.
IT SOUNDS LIKE FROM WHAT WE'RE
READING, SHE WAS OUT ENOUGH TO
NOT EVEN DO THAT.
SHE HIT HER HEAD ON THE WAY DOWN
OR ON THE GROUND ITSELF AND TO
CAUSE A CONCUSSION CAN.
AND, AGAIN, A CONCUSSION DOES
NOT MEAN YOU LOST CONSCIOUSNESS.
A CONCUSSION CAN SIMPLY MEAN
THAT YOU'RE A LITTLE BIT OUT OF
IT, YOU MAY HAVE BLURRY VISION,
RINGING IN YOUR EARS, A HARD
TIME REMEMBERING WORDS FOR A FEW
MINUTES, THINGS LIKE THAT.
BUT THAT'S USUALLY ENOUGH FOR IT
TO BE CALLED A CONCUSSION AND TO
GET AT LEAST AN EXAM.
SOME SORT OF NEUROLOGICAL EXAM.
I DON'T KNOW IF SHE GOT A C.A.T.
SCAN BUT THAT WOULD BE THE
TYPICAL COURSE.
>> SHE'S BEING MONITORED
REGULARLY BY HER DOCTORS.
ACCORDING TO THE STATEMENT,
SHE'S AT HOME.
I ASSUME SHE'S BEING MONITORED
AT HOME BY HER DOCTORS AS
OPPOSED TO GOING TO THE
HOSPITAL.
>> AND THAT'S CLEARLY A GOOD
SIGN.
MOST WOULD SAY IF THEY HAD A
HEIGHTENED CONCERN, IT'S BEST
THAT YOU STAY IN THE HOSPITAL
AND WE CAN OBSERVE YOU.
BUT THE KEY IS THAT USUALLY
SOMEONE WANTS TO BE -- THEY NEED
TO CHECK THE PERSON EVERY HOUR
OR SO AND DO A NEUROLOGICAL
EXAM.
>> WALK US THROUGH -- SECRETARY
CLINTON FAINTED, SHE'S GOT A
STOMACH VIRUS, SHE HIT HER HEAD.
WHAT WOULD YOU DO?
HOW WOULD YOU TEST WITHOUT GOING
THROUGH A C.A.T. SCAN OR
ANYTHING BUYING LIKE THAT?
>> AS SIMPLE AS IT SOUNDS, THAT
IS CERTAINLY PART OF IT.
FIRST OF ALL, YOU WANT TO
ADDRESS THE FAINTING THING SO
SHE MIGHT NEED SOME FLUIDS.
SOMETIMES SOMEONE WOULD NEED AN
I.V. TO GET REHYDRATED.
THAT'S THE FUNDAMENTAL PROBLEM.
AS FAR AS THE NEUROLOGICAL
PROBLEM, WHAT A CONCUSSION MEANS
IS THE WAY THAT YOU INTERPRET
THE WORLD HAS BEEN ALTERED IN
SOME WAY, DECREASE CESSATION.
YOU DO EXACTLY WHAT YOU'RE
SAYING, EYE MOVEMENTS, CHECK
HEARING, ASK THEM QUESTIONS,
MAKE SURE THAT THEY ARE ORIENTED
TO WHO THEY ARE, WHERE THEY ARE,
THE TIME THAT IT IS.
SO THESE SORTS OF QUESTIONS.
AFTER A WHILE YOU GET A PRETTY
GOOD IDEA.
MY GUESS IS THAT HER VISION IS
NORMAL AND THEY WANT TO MAKE
SURE THAT IT STAYS NORMAL.
>> OTHERWISE THEY WOULD HAVE
TAKEN HER TO THE HOSPITAL?
>> EXACTLY.
>> LET'S HOPE THAT SHE RECOVERS
COMPLETELY.
WE ASSUME SHE WILL.
SHE WAS SUPPOSED TO TESTIFY ON
DECEMBER 20th ON THE BENGHAZI.
I ASSUME SHE'S IN NO SITUATION
TO GO TO CAPITOL HILL AND
TESTIFY.
>> IT SOUNDS LIKE FROM WHAT HER
DOCTORS ARE SAYING IS THEY WANT
HER AT HOME FOR ABOUT A WOEEK.
>> LET HER REST AND RECOVER.
I TRAVELED WITH HER ON ONE TRIP
TO FRANCE AND I SAW HOW HARD SHE
WORKS.
>> TIRE YOU OUT EVEN, WOLF IN.
>> I WAS EXHAUSTED BUT SHE KEPT
ON MOVING AND MOVING.
WE, OF COURSE, WISH SECRETARY OF
STATE HILLARY CLINTON A SPEEDY
RECOVERY.
SHE'S SUFFERING FROM A STOMACH
VIRUS, BECAME DEHYDRATED,
FAINTED, AND SUSTAINED A
CONCUSSION.
SHE'S AT HOME RECOUPING AND
DOCTORS ARE TAKING CARE OF HER.
>>> WE'RE HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE WATCHING THIS HORRIFIC
TRAGEDY UNFOLD.
THERE IS NEW INFORMATION COMING
OUT.
WE'RE STANDING BY, BY THE WAY,
FOR A NEWS CONFERENCE.
WE EXPECT TO GET THE NAMES OF
THE VICTIMS.
20 CHILDREN, FOR EXAMPLE, 20 OF
THOSE 26 PEOPLE SHOT IN THIS
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL BEHIND ME HERE
IN CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE GOING TO GET THOSE NAMES
FAIRLY SOON.
THIS IS A MASSACRE THAT HAS
RESONATED NOT ONLY HERE BUT
AROUND THE COUNTRY.
JOSH LEVS IS JOINING US.
>> WE LOST WOLF.
I'M GOING TO TAKE OVER.
HERE'S WHAT I WANT TO TALK TO
YOU ABOUT.
THIS IS VICTIMS AND SURVIVORS OF
COLUMBINE.
14 YEARS AGO.
A LOT OF YOU MIGHT NOT REALIZE,
BE PEOPLE WHO WERE AT THAT
MASSACRE, TWO PEOPLE CAME TO
SCHOOL AND KILLED 14 PEOPLE
BEFORE TAKING THEIR LIVES.
NOW MANY PEOPLE WHO SURVIVED
COLUMBINE ARE OLD ENOUGH TO HAVE
PEOPLE IN SCHOOL.
I SPOKE TO SOME OF THESE
SURVIVORS ABOUT HOW THEY ARE
AFFECTED ABOUT THIS NEWS OUT OF
CONNECTICUT.
I WANT TO INTRODUCE YOU TO A
WOMAN WHO IS A SURVIVOR FROM
COLUMBINE, NOW A MOTHER, KACEY
JOHNSON.
>> YOU LOSE THE SENSE THAT
THINGS CAN NEVER HAPPEN TO YOU.
PARENTS WILL SAY, THIS WOULD
NEVER HAPPEN TO ME.
FOR ME AS A PARENT OF A CHILD, I
BELIEVE THIS COULD EASILY HAPPEN
AT MY CHILD'S SCHOOL BUT THAT'S
BECAUSE IT HAS HAPPENED TO ME
BEFORE.
I WOULD HOPE THAT THE PEOPLE
INVOLVED WILL WALK BESIDE THESE
CHILDREN AND THE FAMILIES FOR
THE YEARS TO COME.
THEY HAVE YEARS AND YEARS OF
HEALING THAT THEY ARE GOING TO
BE FACING.
AND I HOPE THAT WE CAN COME
BESIDE THEM AND ENCOURAGE THEM
AND FOCUS POSITIVELY ON THE
LIVES OF THE ONES THAT WERE
LOST.
>> AND THANK TO KCEY FOR THE
BEAUTIFUL PICTURES OF HER
FAMILY.
ANOTHER PERSON I WANT TO TALK
ABOUT IS SHAWN GRAVES WHO LIVES
IN A WHEELCHAIR.
I SPOKE WITH HIM ABOUT THE
EFFECT THAT THIS NEWS HAS ON
HIM.
>> I LIVE WITH PAIN PHYSICALLY
ON A DAILY BASIS BECAUSE OF THE
INJURIES THAT I SUSTAINED, BUT
LOOKING BACK, I TRY NOT TO THINK
ABOUT IT.
BUT WHEN SOMETHING LIKE THIS
HAPPENS, THAT'S THE FIRST THING
YOU REALLY DO, YOU BEGIN TO
RELIVE IT.
AND TURNING IT ON TO THE --
PUTTING ON THE NEWS AND JUST
WATCHING THE COVERAGE LIVE FROM
THIS POINT OF VIEW VERSUS WHERE
I WAS THEN, IT WILL TAKE YOU
THROUGH AN EMOTIONAL TOLL,
THAT'S FOR SURE.
IT TORE ME DOWN.
>> I WANT YOU ALL TO KNOW THAT
MEMBERS OF THAT GROUP, THE SMALL
GROUP OF PEOPLE WHO REALLY
UNDERSTAND WHAT IT IS LIKE TO BE
INSIDE A SCHOOL WHEN A SCHOOL
DAY TURNS INTO CARNAGE,
PARTICULARLY THERE IN COLUMBINE,
HAVE CREATED ORGANIZATIONS
HELPING PEOPLE IN CONNECTICUT
AND, WOLF, I WAS SPEAKING WITH
SEVERAL OF THEM AND THEY WERE
TELLING ME THAT THEY WANT TO DO
ALL THEY CAN TO HELP THE
FAMILIES MOVE FORWARD AND NOT
JUST TO BE THERE WITH THEM IN
THE SHORT TERM BUT TO BE THERE
WITH THEM IN THE LONG TERM,
WOLF.
>> I THINK THEY CAN HELP,
INDEED.
I THINK THESE PEOPLE HAVE LIVED
THROUGH HELL AND MAYBE THEY CAN
HELP SOME OF THESE PEOPLE HERE
IN CONNECTICUT.
JOSH, THANKS VERY MUCH FOR THAT
REPORT.
WE'RE GOING TO CONTINUE TO
FOLLOW THE REACTION.
WE'RE ALSO -- REMEMBER, WE'RE
STANDING BY.
ANOTHER NEWS CONFERENCE EXPECTED
HERE FAIRLY SOON.
THEY ARE GOING TO BE RELEASING
THE NAMES OF THE VICTIMS,
INCLUDING 20 CHILDREN, SIX
ADULTS.
LET'S CHECK IN WITH DEB
DEBRA FEYRICK.
>> 400 AMERICAN FORCES AND TWO
PATRIOT MISSILE BATTERIES WILL
ARRIVE IN TURKEY SOON.
IT WILL BE UNDER THE CONTROL OF
NATO.
THEY ASKED FOR THIS AS A
DEFENSIVE MEASURE.
IN EGYPT, PRESIDENT MOHAMED H
MORSI DECIDING WHETHER THE
CONTROVERSIAL DOCUMENT GOES INTO
EFFECT.
THE DAYS LEADING UP TO TODAY'S
VOTE HAS BEEN MARRED BY MANY
PROTESTS AND VIOLENCE.
>>> A MASS WAS HELD TODAY FOR A
NURSE THAT HUNG HERSELF AFTER A
PRANK CALL.
HER HUSBAND AND CHILDREN SPOKE
PUBLICLY FOR THE FIRST TIME
SINCE HER DEATH.
JACINTHCA TOOK THE HOAX CALL.
THE FUNERAL WILL BE HELD ON
MONDAY IN SOUTHERN INDIA.
WOLF.
>> DEB, THANKS VERY MUCH.
HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW RIGHT NOW.
THE BODIES OF ALL 26 VICTIMS,
SIX CHILDREN, SIX ADULTS HAVE
BEEN TAKEN OUT OF THE SCHOOL AND
TRANSPORTED TO THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER'S OFFICE IN
CONNECTICUT.
INVESTIGATORS WILL REMAIN AT THE
SCHOOL FOR AT LEAST THE NEXT DAY
OR TWO.
THEY ARE STILL GATHERING
EVIDENCE.
THE IDENTITIES OF THE VICTIMS
WILL BE RELEASED SHORTLY.
WE'RE STANDING BY FOR A NEWS
CONFERENCE.
WE'LL HAVE LIVE COVERAGE HERE ON
CNN.
POLICE SAY THEY HAVE IDENTIFIED
THE SHOOTER AS A 20-YEAR-OLD,
ADAM LANZA.
THEY SAY HE FORCED HIS WAY INTO
THE SCHOOL.
THEY ARE NOT REVEALING EXACTLY
HOW HE GOT IN, AT LEAST NOT YET.
POLICE ALSO SAY THEY FOUND WHAT
THEY DESCRIBE AS GOOD EVIDENCE,
THEIR WORDS, GOOD EVIDENCE ABOUT
HOW LANZA MANAGED TO GET INTO
THE SCHOOL AND COMMIT THIS
DEADLY RAMPAGE, WHY HE DID SO AS
WELL.
THEY ARE REVEALING THAT THERE
WERE THREE GUNS, THREE GUNS
FOUND, THREE WEAPONS FOUND
INSIDE THE SCHOOL NEAR THE
BODIES.
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS PROMISING TO
TAKE WHATEVER STEPS ARE
NECESSARY AND TO PREVENT
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS ONE DOWN THE
ROAD.
HE WANTS TO MAKE SURE THAT
THINGS ARE DONE TO PREVENT FROM
HAPPENING AGAIN.
OUR WHITE HOUSE SPOKESMAN, BEE
BRIANNA KEILAR IS JOINING US.
WHAT DOES HE MEAN BY SPECIFIC
ACTION?
>> Reporter: SPECIFICALLY I
DON'T KNOW.
WHEN HE SAID THAT YESTERDAY IN
THE BRIEFING ROOM AND AGAIN
DURING HIS WEEKLY ADDRESS, IT'S
A GENERAL PROMISE TO DO
SOMETHING TO TRY TO AVERT
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS ONE.
AND I WILL TELL YOU AT THE WHITE
HOUSE, CERTAINLY BEYOND THE
WHITE HOUSE, THERE IS A SENSE
THAT WHAT IS IN PLACE ISN'T
WORKING.
I MEAN, PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS BEEN
PRESIDENT AND SORT OF OVERSEEN
OR HAD TO STRIKE A TONE OF
SENSELESS TRAGEDIES, FROM FT.
HOOD TO THE SHOOTING OF GABBY
GIFFORDS.
AND THIS SCENE AS WELL TAKES IT
TO A NEW LEVEL BECAUSE OF NOT
ONLY TRAGIC CRIME.
I'VE BEEN TALKING TO SOME
SOURCES WHO ARE FAMILIAR WITH
THE OPTIONS THAT THE PRESIDENT
MAY HAVE AT HIS DISPOSAL.
HE HAS TALKED ABOUT RENEWING A
BAN ON SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPONS.
THERE'S THAT.
THERE'S ALSO BEEN TALK OF
PERHAPS LIMITING THE NUMBER OF
BULLETS AND MAGAZINES OF PERHAPS
MOVING FORWARD WITH BETTER
LEGISLATION WHEN IT COMES TO
MENTAL HEALTH, IDENTIFYING
PEOPLE WHO SHOULDN'T HAVE ACCESS
TO WEAPONS, DOING BETTER
REPORTING OF THOSE PEOPLE AND
THE DETAILS OF THIS PARTICULAR
SITUATION, AND THAT WILL INFORM
THE CITIZENS.
>> THE FAMILIES WHO ARE
SUFFERING SO OH MUCH, WILL HE
VISIT THEM?
>> NO WORD BUT IT'S SAFE TO SAY
THAT HE WILL MAKE THAT TRIP.
HE'S DONE THAT IN SITUATIONS
LIKE THIS.
IT'S NORMALLY A FEW DAYS THAT
HAVE PASSED BEFORE HE DOES THAT.
HE'S IN CONTACT WITH STATE
OFFICIALS.
HE'S CERTAINLY TAKING CUES FROM
THEM AND WILL BE IN COORDINATION
WITH THEM AS HE TRIES TO FIGURE
OUT EXACTLY WHETHER AND WHEN HE
WILL BE GOING TO CONNECTICUT,
WOLF.
>> I'M SURE HE'LL BE HERE SOONER
RATHER THAN LATER, BRIANNA.
THANKS VERY, VERY MUCH.
HERE IS THE KEY QUESTION.
WHY?
IT'S A QUESTION ALL OF US ARE
ASKING, ALL OF US ARE STRUGGLING
TO MAKE SENSE OUT OF THE CARNAGE
OUT OF THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
WE'RE GOING TO TALK TO RANDY WHO
EXPERIENCED A SHOOTING INSIDE
HIS CHURCH.
WE'LL SPEAK WITH THE PASTOR WHEN
WE COME BACK.
[ Woman ] DEAR CAT, YOUR HAIR
MIXES WITH POLLEN AND DUST.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
HE LOVES RISK.
BUT WHETHER
HE'S CLIMBING EVEREST,
SCUBA DIVING THE
GREAT BARRIER REEF WITH SHARKS,
OR JUMPING INTO THE MARKET,
HE GOES WITH PEOPLE HE TRUSTS,
WHICH IS WHY HE TRADES
WITH A COMPANY
THAT DOESN'T NICKEL AND DIME
HIM WITH HIDDEN FEES.
SO HE CAN WORRY
ABOUT OTHER THINGS,
LIKE WHAT THE MARKET IS DOING
AND BEING READY,
NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENS,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE,
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
Bye!
Santa, we made a video for
your trip!
Yeah, you can watch it on your
sleigh!
OK!
Here you go.
Aw, thanks elves.
I also made you a video.
You are so sweet.
But you probably shouldn't watch
it on the sleigh.
Say goodbye to Santa boys!
Bye!
Good bye Santa!
Exclusively at AT&T, buy any
Samsung Galaxy smartphone,
get up to $100 off a second
msung Galaxy device.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
.
>>> INDICAKATE BOLDUAN IS JOINI
ON THE PHONE.
KATE, WHAT ARE YOU LEARNING
SPECIFICALLY ABOUT THE VICTIMS?
>> HEY THERE, WOLF.
I JUST LEFT A VERY EE MOWING MO
INTERVIEW WITH ONE OF THE PARENT
OF VICKY SOTO'S STUDENTS.
DURING THIS INTERVIEW THEY TOLD
ME WHAT IS TRULY A MIRACULOUS
STORY OF HOW THEIR SON MADE IT
OUT OF THAT SCHOOL ALIVE AND HOW
VICKY SOTO WAS ABLE TO PROTECT
AND SAVE SO MANY -- SAVE THEIR
SON AND OTHER STUDENTS FROM THE
SHOOTER.
ACCORDING TO THESE PARENTS,
THEIR SON HAS RECOUNTED THAT
ONCE IT WAS CLEAR THAT A SHOOTER
WAS IN THE SCHOOL, SHE MOVED THE
STUDENTS IN HER CLASSROOM TO THE
FAR END OF THE ROOM AWAY FROM
THE DOOR.
THE SHOOTER THEN BURST THROUGH
THE DOOR AND SHOT HER TEACHER,
VICKY SOTO, IN FRONT OF HER
STUDENTS.
THIS IS A FIRST GRADE CLASS THAT
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT.
I THINK WE HAVE A PHOTO THAT WE
CAN SHOW YOU.
THIS IS OF VICKY SOTO AND THIS
IS FROM A CLASS PHOTO THIS YEAR.
SOMEHOW, WOLF, THIS LITTLE BOY
AND SOME OF HIS FELLOW STUDENT,
HIS CLASSMATES, WERE ABLE TO RUN
RIGHT PAST -- DIRECTLY PAST THE
SHOOTER WHILE HE WAS THERE AND
THEY WERE ABLE TO GET OUT OF THE
SCHOOL.
THEY RAN STRAIGHT OUT OF THE
SCHOOL FROM THERE AND EVENTUALLY
MADE IT TO SAFETY.
A REALLY HARROWING TALE THAT WAS
JUST TOLD TO ME AND, OF COURSE,
AT THIS POINT MISS SOTO IS
FEARED TO BE AMONG THE DEAD.
WE DO NOT HAVE CONFIRMATION OF
THAT AND YOU CAN BE SURE THAT
THIS LITTLE BOY AND HIS PARENT
DON'T KNOW AND THEY, OF COURSE,
HOPE FOR THE BEST.
BUT IT WAS REALLY MOVING TO HEAR
HOW THEIR 6-YEAR-OLD SON LOVED
HER AND WHAT SHE DID TO PROTECT
HER STUDENTS AND SHE HERSELF POE
TECHNICALLY FATALLY INJURED IN
DOING SO, WOLF.
>> HOW WERE THE PARENTS --
HOW -- I KNOW THAT YOU'VE BEEN
SPEAKING WITH PEOPLE SINCE YOU
GOT HERE, KATE.
HOW ARE THEY COPING?
HOW DO THEY SEEM TO BE DURING
YOUR CONVERSATION?
>> IT RANGES FROM ABSOLUTE
RELIEF.
YOU KNOW, I MET THEIR TWO
CHILDREN.
THIS ONE FAMILY -- THEY HAVE TWO
KIDS THAT WERE AT THE SCHOOL.
A FIRST GRADER AND A SECOND
GRADER.
AND JUST SEEING THEM TRYING TO
GO BACK -- TO GO ABOUT A NORMAL
SCHEDULE, TRY TO WATCH CARTOONS
IN THE MORNING AND PANCAKES THIS
MORNING.
THE RELIEF ON THEIR FACES IS
JUST AS MUCH SHARED WITH THE
GRIEF WHEN THEY KNOW THAT OTHER
FAMILIES THIS MORNING ARE NOT
ABLE TO TRY TO GET ANY KIND OF
SEMBLANCE TO NORMALCY.
THEY ACCEPT THE FACT THAT THEY
HAVE NOT BEEN ABLE TO REGISTER
WHAT IS HAPPENING AND WHAT THIS
TOWN WILL NEVER BE THE SAME.
IT IS A VERY CLOSE-KNIT
COMMUNITY.
THEIR SON AND DAUGHTER MADE IT
OUT SAFELY AND THEY SAY THAT
THEY ARE ANGELS ON THEIR
SHOULDERS YESTERDAY MORNING.
SO MANY OTHER CHILDREN DID NOT
AND THEY ARE VERY AWARE OF THAT
AND THAT'S WHY THEY WANTED TO
SIT DOWN AND SPEAK WITH US, JUST
TO SEND THEIR LOVE AND SUPPORT
TO THE COMMUNITY AND ALL TRY TO
PROVIDE HEALING WHEN IT'S STILL
HARD TO WRAP THEIR MIND AROUND
WHAT HAPPENED, HOW THAT EVIL
COULD ENTER THAT CLASSROOM AND
STARE DOWN THOSE CHILDREN.
>> KATE'S GOING TO BE BACK WITH
US FOR OUR SPECIAL COVERAGE.
KATE WILL BE WITH ME AND SHE'LL
HAVE THAT INTERVIEW FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
5:00 TO 8:00 P.M. EASTERN.
RIGHT NOW I'M JOINED BY THE
SENATOR OF CONNECTICUT.
I ASSUME YOU WERE HERE WHEN YOU
HEARD ABOUT WHAT WAS GOING ON.
CAN YOU SHEAR WITH OUR VIEWERS,
THE KEY QUESTION WHY?
WAS THERE ANY MOTIVE THAT COULD
HAVE CAUSED THIS TRAGEDY?
>> I WAS ATTORNEY GENERAL FOR 20
YEARS AND FEDERAL PROSECUTOR
BEFORE THAT AND I CAN TELL YOU
THAT THAT IS ONE OF THE KEY
QUESTIONS.
THERE ARE NO ANSWERS AS YET.
ONE OF THE CHALLENGES IS, THERE
IS SO LITTLE DIRECT EVIDENCE
THAT REFLECTS ON MOTIVE BUT
OBVIOUSLY THE HORROR AND THE
GRIEF IS VERY REAL AND I THINK
ALL OF OUR HEARTS ARE GOING OUT
TO THOSE.
>> DO WE KNOW IF THERE WAS A
SUICIDE LETTER OR ANYTHING ALONG
THOSE LINES?
>> AS OF YET, THERE IS NO DIRECT
EVIDENCE THAT I CAN SHARE AT
THIS POINT.
THE INVESTIGATION IS ONGOING.
I CAN BRIEF REGULARLY AS
RECENTLY AS JUST A LITTLE WHILE
AGO.
THE INVESTIGATION CONTINUING
VERY ACTIVELY INVOLVING THE HOME
OF THE SHOOTER AS WELL AS --
>> WHERE HIS MOTHER IS DEAD.
THIS 20-YEAR-OLD SHOT HIS MOTHER
AT THE HOME AND THEN DROVE TO
THE SCHOOL AND OPENED FIRE ON
THESE KIDS.
>> THAT IS THE TIMELINE OF WHAT
OCCURRED.
THAT'S GENERALLY WHAT HAPPENED
AND THIS KIND OF MADNESS HAS NO
IMMEDIATE OR APPARENT
EXPLANATION AND THE TRAGEDY IS
INEXPLICABLE.
AT THE SERVICE LAST NIGHT --
>> AT THE VIGIL AT THE CHURCH?
>> YES, AT THE CHURCH, SENIOR
WEISS, AS YOU KNOW, BEGAN WITH
THE QUESTION WHY?
AND THERE IS NO ANSWER AT THIS
POINT.
>> THERE MAY NEVER BE AN ANSWER
TO THAT QUESTION BECAUSE
SOMETIMES WE DON'T KNOW AND
THAT'S THAT.
BUT CONNECTICUT DOES HAVE PRETTY
STRICT GUN CONTROL LAWS ON THE
BOOKS RIGHT NOW.
BUT WHAT ELSE DO YOU NEED TO DO?
YOU WERE THE ATTORNEY GENERAL
FOR A LONG TIME IN THIS STATE.
WHAT ELSE CAN BE DONE TO TRY TO
REDUCE THE CHANCES THAT THIS
COULD HAPPEN AT ANOTHER
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL?
>> WELL, AS ATTORNEY GENERAL I
FOUGHT FOR GUN SAFETY MEASURES,
ASSAULT WITH A BAN IS A MEASURE
THAT I DEFENDED IN COURT WHEN IT
WAS CHALLENGED CONSTITUTIONALLY,
PERSONALLY WENT TO COURT TO
DEFEND IT AND I THINK THAT'S A
CONVERSATION THAT WE WILL HAVE
IN THIS STATE AND AROUND THE
COUNTRY, WHAT GREATER MEASURES
IN ENFORCEMENT AND IN NEW KINDS
OF OVERSIGHT CAN ACHIEVE SAFETY,
PARTICULARLY IN OUR SCHOOLS
WHERE OBVIOUSLY A TRAGEDY OF
THIS KIND IS BEYOND WORDS AND
BEYOND COMPREHENSION.
>> SUSAN CANDIOTTI, OUR
REPORTER, SAID THEY FOUND THREE
WEAPONS ON THE SCENE BUT THEY
THINK THAT THERE ARE OTHER
WEAPONS ELSEWHERE.
HAVE YOU HEARD THAT?
>> THERE WAS A FOURTH WEAPON
RECOVERED IN THE CAR.
THREE WEAPONS ON THE SCENE.
TWO OF THEM HANDGUNS, SIG SAUER,
A GLOCK, AND THEN A CIVILIAN
MODIFICATION OF THE M-16.
SO THERE WERE THREE WEAPONS ON
THE SCENE.
>> WERE ALL OF THEM USED?
>> AND ALL OF THEM WERE USED IN
SOME WAY DURING THE SHOOTING.
>> DO YOU KNOW IF HE USED ALL OF
THE AMMUNITION THAT HE HAD OR
WAS THERE STILL AMMUNITION
AVAILABLE TO HIM?
>> I CAN'T SAY WHETHER THAT WAS
SO.
WHETHER ALL OF THE AMMUNITION
WAS USED OR NOT.
>> BUT THESE WEAPONS WERE
REGISTERED IN HIS MOTHER'S NAME?
IS THAT RIGHT?
>> I CAN'T CONFIRM WHETHER THEY
WERE COMPLETELY REGULARLY
REGISTERED BUT I'M TOLD AT LEAST
ONE WAS REGISTERED IN HER NAME.
>> HAVE YOU BEEN IN TOUCH WITH
THE WHITE HOUSE, THE PRESIDENT?
I'M ASSUMING HE'LL BE CAN COMING
HERE, THERE WILL BE AN
OPPORTUNITY FOR HIM TO CONSOLE
THE FAMILIES OF THOSE WHO KIDS
DIED.
>> I CAN TELL YOU THAT THE
PRESIDENT'S HEART AND PRAYER ARE
WITH YOU NEWTOWN AT THIS MOMENT.
WE'VE BEEN IN TOUCH WITH THE
WHITE HOUSE.
THE TIMING OF HIS VISIT IS NOT
YET SET, SO FAR AS I KNOW, IF IN
FACT HE WILL BE COMING.
THIS WHOLE EPISODE IS IS SO
EXTRAORDINARY, AT LEAST IN THE
EXPERIENCE OF MOST PEOPLE.
THERE MAY BE OTHERS AROUND THE
WORLD THAT HAVE OCCURRED, A
COMPARABLE TRAGEDY.
BUT 20 LITTLE CHILDREN.
I THINK THE PRESIDENT WANTS TO
BE RESPECTFUL OF THE GRIEF AND
THE KINDS OF EXPERIENCE THAT IS
REFLECTED HERE.
>> DO YOU HAVE A HISTORY HERE IN
THIS COMMUNITY?
DANBURY IS NOT VERY FAR AWAY.
YOU WERE THE ATTORNEY GENERAL,
YOU'RE THE SENATOR.
DID YOU KNOW ANY OF THESE
VICTIMS?
>> I CAN'T SAY I KNEW THE
VICTIMS OR THEIR PARENTS BUT I
KNOW THE COMMUNITY WELL.
IT'S A STRONG COMMUNITY.
IT'S A GREAT SMALL TOWN IN
CONNECTICUT.
AND I'M HERE QUITE A BIT AS WELL
AS IN DANBURY.
REALLY ALL AROUND THE STATE.
BUT IT HAS THE STRENGTH AND
COURAGE THAT IT HAS
DEMONSTRATED.
>> ONE OTHER QUESTION.
YOU'RE GOING TO GO BACK TO
WASHINGTON.
UNITED STATES SENATE.
IS NEW FEDERAL LEGISLATION
NEEDED TO TIGHTEN UP GUN CONTROL
IN THE UNITED STATES?
>> YOU KNOW, WOLF, I THINK THAT
IS A CONVERSATION I'M GOING TO
HAVE WITH MY COLLEAGUES.
AND TODAY I'M NOT GOING TO
DISCUSS THAT OUT OF RESPECT TO
THE FAMILIES AND I'M GOING TO BE
BACK BE AGAIN TOMORROW.
BUT I'M GOING TO GO TO
WASHINGTON AND I'M GOING TO
RAISE THIS ISSUE AND I THINK
IT'S TIME FOR THE CONVERSATION
TO BE RENEWED FOR THE DIALOGUE
TO BEGIN AGAIN AND FOR THE
SENATE TO CONSIDER WHETHER THAT
KIND OF ACTION IS NECESSARY.
>> SENATOR BLUMENTHAL, THANK YOU
FOR COMING IN.
>> THANK YOU.
>> OUR DEEP CONDOLENCES TO
EVERYONE IN THE STATE.
THEY ARE SUFFERING AND SO ARE
WE.
>> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR BEING HERE.
>>> THAT'S IT.
WHAT A HORRIFIC STORY.
WHAT ELSE COULD I SAY?
I WILL BE BACK LATER.
A SPECIAL THREE-HOUR "THE
SITUATION ROOM" STARTING AT 5:00
P.M. EASTERN UNTIL 8:00 P.M.
OUR COVERAGE WILL CONTINUE.
ALSO WE'RE FOLLOWING THE LATEST
OF SECRETARY HILLARY CLINTON.
SHE SUFFERED A CONCUSSION.
SHE FAINTED.
SHE'S RECOVERING AT HER HOME IN
WASHINGTON.
OUR COVERAGE CONTINUES RIGHT
AFTER THIS.
From the best
players in history
to the number 1 club
in the world.
The potential of
Manchester United unlocked.
NYSE Euronext.
Unlocking the world's potential.
YOU WON'T TAKE OUR FUTURE.
AIDS AFFECTS US ALL.
EVEN BABIES.
CHEVRON IS WORKING TO STOP
MOTHER-TO-CHILD TRANSMISSION.
OUR EMPLOYEES AND THEIR FAMILIES
ARE PART OF THE FIGHT.
AND WE'RE WINNING.
AT CHEVRON NIGERIA, WE HAVEN'T
HAD A REPORTED CASE IN 12 YEARS.
AIDS IS STRONG.
BUT WE ARE STRONGER.
AND AIDS...
♪
AIDS IS GOING TO LOSE.