FOR YOU.
CALL 1-855-999-1399
OR VISIT EXELONPATCHOFFER2.COM.
>>> GOOD AFTERNOON, EVERYONE,
YOU ARE WATCHING CNN LIVE
SPECIAL COVERAGE OF THE TRAGEDY
THAT HAS SHOCKED OUR NATION AND
SHOCKED THIS SMALL TOWN OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
I'M ANDERSON COOPER LIVE THIS
AFTERNOON IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> AND I'M WOLF BLITZER ALSO
HERE IN NEWTOWN.
THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES IS ON HIS WAY HERE RIGHT
NOW TO THIS COMMUNITY THRUSTED
TO THE HISTORY BOOKS BY A
HORRIBLE ACT OF VIOLENCE.
THE PRESIDENT WILL MEET WITH,
TRY TO COMFORT FAMILIES OF 20
SCHOOL KIDS AND SIX ADULTS.
WE ARE ALL SHOT DEAD HERE FRIDAY
MORNING.
>> A SHORT TIME AGO GOT AN
UPDATE FROM THE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE, LEARNED MORE
DETAILS ABOUT THE PERSON WHO
CARRIED OUT THIS MASS SHOOTING
THEY CAN DID CONFIRM SEVERAL
DETAILS THAT THEY BELIEVED WERE
TRUE SINCE FRIDAY.
THE SHOOTER'S NAME YOU OF COURSE
WHAT KIND OF WEAPONS WE HAD WITH
HIM AND JUST HOW MANY MORE
BULLETS COULD HAVE FIRED.
THE NUMBER IS EXTRAORDINARILY
HIGH.
>> STAY THERE.
WE ARE GOING TO TELL YOU EXACTLY
WHERE POLICE STAND IN THEIR
INVESTIGATION AND SO MANY
QUESTIONS THAT CERTAINLY REMAIN
UNANSWERED.
THESE QUESTIONS, I'M NOT SURE WE
ARE EVER GOING TO GET REAL
ANSWERS TO.
>> YEAH WOLF, TRYING TO PIECE
THIS TOGETHER AS MUCH AS WE CAN,
AS CAREFULLY AS WE CAN.
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS EN ROUTE TO
THIS SMALL TOWN NOW TO JOIN THE
PEOPLE OF KNUTEN IN THEIR GRIEF.
GREEFT HERE IS OVERWHELMING.
HE WILL ATTEND A VIGIL AT A
CHURCH HERE, MEET WITH PARENTS
AND LOVED ONES OF THE PEOPLE
KILLED.
THE WHITE HOUSE SAYS HE WANTS TO
PERSONALLY THANK THE FIRST
RESPONDERS, THOSE PEOPLE WHO
POLICE AND PARAMEDICS CREDITED
WITH PRESENT VENTING THIS AWFUL
STRATEGY FROM BEING WORSE.
>> NANCY LANZA, THE GUNMAN'S
MOTHER, SHOT DEAD FRIDAY MORNING
IN HER HOME.
SHE WAS SUN SOMEONE WHO LIKED TO
GARDEN AND PLAY A DICE CAME
CALLED BUNKO.
DON LEMON JOINING US NOW.
YOU SPOKE WITH FOUR OF HER
FRIENDS ABOUT HER PERSONALITY,
HER APPROACH TO MOTHERHOOD.
STANDING BY TO GET THAT
INFORMATION FROM DON.
DON HAS BEEN WORKING THE STORY
AND CONNECT WITH DON AS SOON AS
WE CAN.
AS WE WATCH ALL OF THESE
DEVELOPMENTS UNFOLD, YOU AND I
HAVE BEEN HERE NOW FOR A COUPLE
OF DAYS, IRGOT TO TELL YOU
DOESN'T GET EASIER, BUT MORE
PAINFUL BY THE HOUR AS WE LEARN
DETAILS OF THE SIX ADULTS, ALL
WOMEN, 20 KIDS, FIRST GRADERS,
AGES 6 AND 7 WHO WERE KILLED.
>> JUST YESTERDAY ALL THE NAMES
WERE RELEASED BY POLICE.
YOU GO DOWN THE LIST, YOU SEE
THE NAMES AND THE AGES, 6 YEARS
OLD, 7 YEARS OLD, JUST PERSON
AFTER PERSON, CHILD AFTER CHILD,
IT IS STILL JUST SO HARD TO
UNDERSTAND.
WE ARE LEARNING ABOUT EACH
PERSON KILLED.
ONE PERSON YOU MAY BE FAMILIAR
WITH IS EMILIE PARKER, JUST 6
YEARS OLD.
HER FATHER, ROBERT, SPOKE
PUBLICLY LAST NIGHT, ONE OF THE
ONLY PARENTS TO HAVE COME
FORWARD TO SPEAK PUBLICLY AFTER
THIS TRAGEDY.
HERE IS SOME OF WHAT HE SAID.
>> EMILIE WAS A NOERPT HER TWO
LITTLE SISTERS, DELIGHTING IN
TEACHING THEM,READ, DANCE AND
FIND THE SIMPLE JOYS IN LIFE.
EMILIE'S LAUGHTER WAS INFECTION
AND ALL THOSE WHO HAD THE
PLEASURE TO MEET HER WOULD AGREE
THAT THIS WORLD IS A BETTER
PLACE BECAUSE SHE HAS BEEN IN
IT.
>> FAEPT WEPT ON TO TALK ABOUT
HOW STRONG HIS LITTLE GIRL WAS.
HE HAS TWO OTHER DAUGHTERS.
IMAGINE TRYING TO EXPLAIN THE
LOSS OF EMILIE TO THOSE
DAUGHTERS.
DON LEMON HAS BEEN LEARNING MORE
INFORMATION ABOUT THE -- THE
MOTHER OF THIS HERE IS THE.
DON, WHAT ARE YOU HEARING?
>> HI, ANDERSON, WE ARE HERE
DOWN AT THE SQUARE.
WE HAVE BEEN TALKING TO PEOPLE
AS WELL.
THEY HAVE BEEN COMING UP US TO.
YOU HAVE BEEN WITNESSING THE
SAME THING.
SHOW YOU THE MEMORIAL, WE CAME
HERE, GOT HERE YESTERDAY, WHEN I
DID.
THIS WAS A VERY SMALL MEMORIAL,
JUST 26 CANDLES HERE FOR THE
VICTIMS WHO DIED INSIDE OF THE
SCHOOL AND THERE WERE SOME
PEOPLE WHO WERE ASKING US, WELL,
WHAT ABOUT THE 27th CANDLE, THE
27th CANDLE, REMEMBER THE
SHOOTER'S MOTHER WAS A VICTIM AS
WELL.
HER FRIENDS CAME UP TO US LAST
NIGHT, ANDERSON, AS YOU AND I
WERE ON THE AIR, WE HEARD A LOT
OF THINGS ABOUT HER, A LOT IS
NOT TRUE, WE WANT TO CLEAR THE
RECORD AND WANT PEOPLE TO KNOW
WHO NANCY LANZA IS.
HERE IS WHAT THEY HAD TO SAY
ABOUT HER.
TAKE A LISTEN.
TELL US ABOUT NANCY.
WE DON'T KNOW MUCH ABOUT HER.
>> NANCY WAS JUST A LOVELY
WOMAN, A GREAT FRIEND, YOU KNOW,
WARM PERSONALITY.
YOU KNOW, SHE JUST WOULD MAKE
YOU SMILE WHEN SHE WALKED INTO
THE ROOM.
>> YOU SAID THAT YOU WANTED TO
TALK ABOUT HER BECAUSE THERE'S
SOME THINGS YOU WANTED TO CHEAP
UP FOR US.
>> WELL, I'VE SEEN A LOT OF
THINGS IN THIS THE MEDIA ABOUT
HER BEING THIS SURVIVALIST
WACKO.
THAT WAS NOT HER AT ALL.
SHE DID HAVE GUNS, WHICH SHE
USED VERY RESPONSIBLY.
SHE WENT SHOOTING WITH A FRIEND
OF OURS WHO IS A RETIRED NEW
YORK CITY POLICE OFFICER.
HE TAUGHT HER HOW TO SHOOT.
SHE WAS VERY RESPONSIBLE WITH
THE GUN.
SHE WAS A VERY RESPONSIBLE
PERSON IN GENERAL, ESPECIALLY IN
TERMS OF SAFETY.
>> ELLEN, SHE TOOK THE BOYS TO
THE SHOOTING RANGE.
THAT'S BEEN TALKED ABOUT.
SHE DID TAKE THEM TO THE
SHOOTING RANGE?
>> FROM WHAT I UNDERSTAND, YEP.
>> AND WHAT DID YOU WANT TO SAY
ABOUT THAT?
>> AGAIN, I GUESS I WANT TO J  T
JUST -- UM -- UM -- UM -- UM
MICKIC RUSS AS FAR AS SAFETY.
NANCY WOULDN'T ANSWER HER PHONE
OR LOOK AT A TEXT IN THE CAR.
IF I GOT IN THE CAR, IT WAS
OOPS, SEAT BELT, AT THE FIRST
DIPPI
DING OR BEFORE THE DING
HAPPENED.
SHE WAS VERY CAREFUL AND
CAUTIOUS AND RESPONSIBLE.
IN REGARD TO LEAVING ANYTHING
OUT AS FAR AS A GUN, IT IS -- I
CAN'T BELIEVE SHOW WITH DO THE .
>> SEBASTIAN, TELL US YOUR
MEMORIES?
>> A VERY DIGNIFIED WOMAN, A LOT
OF CLASS, VERY PROPER, GREAT
MORAL COMPASS.
WE JUST SAW HER THREE WEEKS AGO,
MY PLACE, I LEFT, ACCIDENT SAY
BYE.
SHE SEND EMBASSY TEXT ZURNGTS
SAY BYE TO ME.
THE KIND OF PERSON SHE WAS.
VERY POLITE AND NICE TO YOU, A
REALLY GOOD PERSON.
>> SHE WANTED AS NORMAL A LIFE
FOR HER SON AS POSSIBLE.
THERE THEY ARE TALKING ABOUT
HER.
A LITTLE BIT LATER ON, WE WILL
LEARN MORE ABOUT HIM BECAUSE
THEY DID KNOW ABOUT THE SON AND
IT'S INTERESTING, ANDERSON, TO
HEAR WHAT THEY HAVE TO SAY ABOUT
HIM AS WELL.
A LOT OF FOLKS OUT HERE, SOME
PEOPLE BRINGING CHRISTMAS TREES
AND PEOPLE COMING FROM ALL OVER
THE TRISTATE AREA, ALL OVER THE
AREA, ANDERSON, JUST TO PAY
TRIBUTE TO THE VICTIMS AND THEIR
FAMILIES.
>> YEAH, DON, WE SEE A MAKESHIFT
MEMORIAL BY THE HIGH SCHOOL
WHERE I'M AT TONIGHT AS WELL.
THESE HAVE SPRUNG UP ALL AROUND
THIS TOWN, CONNECTICUT, PICTURES
LAST NIGHT IN RIO de JANEIRO
SOME PEOPLE PUT UP NEAR THE
BEACH THERE BROOK BALDWIN IS
JOINING US WITH MORE ON EMILIE
PARKER.
YOU KNOW, BROOKE, A TWEET I SAW
FROM A WRITER AT "USA TODAY" THE
OTHER DAY WHO SAID HOW DO YOU
WRITE AN OBITUARY FOR A
16-YEAR-OLD AND THEN HOW DO YOU
WRITE 19 MORE?
AS WE ARE IS SLOWLY STARTING TO
LEARN MORE AND MORE ABOUT THE
CHILDREN WHOSE LIVES WERE LOST,
THAT'S SOMETHING THAT'S -- YOU
KNOW, HOW DO YOU TALK ABOUT A
6-YEAR-OLD, A 7-YEAR-OLD?
AND BROOK, TO HEAR EMILIE'S
FATHER YESTERDAY COME OUT AND
SPEAK ABOUT HIS LITTLE GIRL, IT
WAS ONE OF THE MOST
HEARTBREAKING THINGS THAT WE
HEARD YESTERDAY.
>> Reporter: IT ABSOLUTELY
BREAKS YOUR HEART, ANDERSON.
WHEN YOU COVER TRAGEDIES AND YOU
SEE THE VICTIMS' LIST AND THEIR
AGES IN THE SINGLE DIGITS, I
THINK THE PRESIDENT PUT IT WELL
ON FRIDAY, TALK ABOUT THESE ARE
YOUNGSTERS, YOUNG BOYS AND YOUNG
GIRLS WHO HAVE YET TO GRADUATE
AND GET MARRIED AND GO ON TO
PERHAPS FULFILLING THEIR OWN
DREAM HE IS OF HAVING CHILDREN.
SO, WHEN YOU READ THESE
DESCRIPTIONS ABOUT THESE YOUNG
PEOPLE, PARENTS SAY THINGS ABOUT
THE COLORS THEY LOVE AND THE
HOBBIES THEY LOVE.
YOU MENTIONED ELIE PACKER.
WE HEARD FROM HER FATHER LAST
NIGHT.
6 YEARS OLD.
LET ME QUOTE THE FATHER AGAIN.
"SHE WAS THE TYPE OF PERSON WHO
COULD LIGHT UP A RADIO.
SHE WAS BRIGHT.
SHE WAS CREATIVE.
SHE WAS LOVING.
HER LAUGHTER WAS INFECTIOUS."
WHAT'S REALLY TOUGH HERE, YOU
LISTEN TO SOME OF THESE YOUNG
PEOPLE, THEY HAVE SIBLINGS.
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN THIS TO
YOUNGER BROTHERS AND SISTERS,
SHE WAS THE OLDEST OF THREE
LITTLE GIRLS.
HER FATHER SAID THAT EMILIE WAS
A MENTOR TO THEM.
THEY LOOKED UP TO HER.
TELL YOU ABOUT JESSICA REKOS
ALSO, 6 YEARS OLD.
IN A STATEMENT TO CNN, THE
FAMILY TOLD US THAT JESSICA WAS
THEIR FIRST BORN, THEY CALLED
HER THEIR ROCK, CALLED HER
FAMILY'S LITTLE CEO BECAUSE
APPARENTLY, SHE LIKED TO PLAN
EVERYTHING.
SHE LIKED ALL THE DETAILS,
HELPING HER FAMILY IN PLANS AND
SHE LOVED EVERYTHING HORSES.
SHE WOULD DRAW HORSES.
SHE WATCHED HORSE MOVIES.
ACCORDING TO HER FAMILY FOR THIS
CHRISTMAS, SHE HAD ASKED SANTA
CLAUS FOR A NEW PAIR OF COWBOY
BOOTS AND A COWBOY HAT.
SHE HAD TWO LITTLE BROTHERS AND
HER BABY BROTHER, TRAVIS,
ACCORDING TO HER PARENTS, JUST
DOESN'T QUITE UNDERSTAND WHERE
HIS BEST FRIEND IS, WHY HE CAN'T
PLAY WITH HIS BEST FRIEND.
THESE ARE JUST SOME OF THE
YOUNGSTERS.
LET ME TELL YOU ABOUT ONE OF THE
TEACHERS HERE, A PERMANENT
SUBSTITUTE TEACHER, HER NAME WAS
LAUREN ROUSSEAU, 30 YEARS OLD.
SHE HAD JUST BEEN AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL FOR SIX WEEKS.
SHE WAS HIRED LAST MONTH AS THE
PERMANENT SUBSTITUTE AND IT WAS
HER CLASSROOM, FOR WHATEVER
REASON, IN WHICH THE SHOOTER
CHOSE TO ENTER FIRST EARLY
FRIDAY MORNING.
ACCORDING TO LAUREN'S MOTHER,
LET ME READ YOU THIS, "LAUREN
WANTED TO BE A TEACHER SINCE
BEFORE SHE WENT TO
KINDERGARTEN," HER MOTHER TAKING
SOME SOLACE KNOWING AT LEAST HER
DAUGHTER FULFILLED HER DREAM IN
BECOMING A TEACHER.
THERE ARE SO MANY STORIES YOU
ANDERSON SO MANY BACKSTORY, WE
WANT TO HONOR ALL THESE LIVES
LOST AND THE GOOD FOLKS AT
CNN.COM PUT UP A WEBSITE.
YOU CAN GO TO CNN.COM, FILL IN
THE PICTURES AND STORIES.
ONE LAST THING HAD I NOTICED
COMING INTO TOWN WITH FRESH
EYES, YOU WALK AROUND, YOU
MENTIONED YOU ARE STANDING AT A
MEMORIAL.
IT IS ONE THING TO WALK AROUND
THIS TOWN AND SEE ADULTS PAYING
TRIBUTE, CARRYING AROUND
CANDLES, DECORATING THE
CHRISTMAS TREE IN THE SQUARE.
IT TAKES YOUR BREATH AWAY TO SEE
4-YEAR-OLDS, 5-YEAR-OLDS,
6-YEAR-OLDS CARRYING STUFFED
ANIMALS BARELY AS LARGE AS THEM,
PLACING THEM DOWN, WIPING TEARS
AWAY.
IT BREAKS YOUR HEART, ANDERSON.
>> YEAH.
WE TALKED TO SO MANY PARENTS WHO
ARE STRUGGLING ABOUT WHAT TO
TELL THEIR CHILDREN ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED AND ABOUT THEIR LITTLE
FRIENDS WHO HAVE DIED AND HOW TO
TELL THEIR CHILDREN THAT.
FOR MORE INFORMATION ON HOW YOU
CAN HELP THOSE AFFECTED, IF
YOU'RE INTERESTED IN DOING THAT
VISIT CNN.COM/IMPACT.
OUR SPECIAL COVERAGE IS GOING TO
CONTINUE NOW, TAKE A SHORT
BREAK, BUT OUR SPECIAL COVERAGE
CONTINUES FROM HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
AMERICANS ARE ALWAYS READY TO
WORK HARD FOR A BETTER FUTURE.
SINCE AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL
WAS FOUNDED BACK IN 1894,
THEY'VE BEEN COMMITTED
TO PUTTING CLIENTS FIRST.
HELPING GENERATIONS
THROUGH TOUGH TIMES.
GOOD TIMES.
NEVER TAKING A BAILOUT.
THERE WHEN YOU NEED THEM.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
OVER THE CENTURIES.
THE STRENGTH OF
A GLOBAL FINANCIAL LEADER.
THE HEART OF
A ONE-TO-ONE RELATIONSHIP.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
WITH ODOR FREE ASPERCREME.
POWERFUL MEDICINE
RELIEVES PAIN FAST,
WITH NO ODOR.
SO ALL YOU NOTICE IS RELIEF.
ASPERCREME.
>>> CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
CONFIRM TODAY, A LITTLE WHILE
AGO INDEED, ADAM LANZA FIRED
WHAT THEY CALL HUNDREDS OF
BULLET, HUNDREDS, AT THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL ON FRIDAY
AND YOU A NUMBER OF WEAPONS WITH
HIM.
LIVE FROM THE LANZA HOME WITH
THAT INVESTIGATION.
ALSO, AWAITING THE ARRIVAL OF
PRESIDENT OBAMA, DUE HERE IN
NEWTOWN SHORTLY, GOING TO SPEAK
WITH THE FAMILIES OF THE 26
PEOPLE, MOST OF THEM ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL CHILDREN WHO WERE SHOT
DEAD FRIDAY MORNING.
STAY WITH CNN FOR THAT YOU WILL
SEE THE PRESIDENT LIVE RIGHT
HERE WHEN HE ARRIVES.
OF COURSE, THE INTERFAITH VIGIL,
THE ENTIRETY, ALL OF IT WE WILL
BRING IT TO YOU LIVE.
GO OUT TO THE HOME WHERE ADAM
LANZA LIVED WITH HIS MOTHER THAT
HOME IS ALSO RIGHT NOW A CRIME
SCENE BECAUSE IT APPEARS IN
LANZA'S MOTHER WAS KILLED --
KILLED IN THE HOME BEFORE THE
SHOOTING RAMPAGE OVER AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
CNN'S ALISON KOSIK JOINING US
FROM THE LANZA HOME.
THE STATE POLICE, CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE, JUST GAVE US AN
UPDATE.
FOR THOSE OF THE VIEWERS WEREN'T
WATCHING CNN LIVE, TELL US THE
MAIN POINTS THAT THE POLICE
MADE.
>> STATE POLICE SAY THAT ADAM
LANZA SHOT AND KILLED HIS
MOTHER, SHOOTING HER MULTIPLE
TIMES INSIDE THE HOUSE, THAT IS
IN THIS NEIGHBORHOOD WHERE I'M
STANDING RIGHT NOW.
POLICE STILL HAVE THE STREET
LEADING UP TO HIS HOUSE BLOCKED
OFF.
YOU KNOW, THERE HASN'T BEEN MUCH
ACTIVITY SINCE YESTERDAY
AFTERNOON, UP UNTIL ABOUT -- I
WOULD SAY A LITTLE OVER AN HOUR
AGO, WE WATCHED ABOUT SIX POLICE
CARS DRIVE UP SEVERAL OFFICIALS
GOT OUT OF THEIR CAR, TALKED A
BUILT AND THEN GOT BACK IN THE
CARS AND DROVE OFF, WE ASSUME TO
ADAM LANZA'S HOUSE.
WE LEARNED FROM STATE POLICE,
THEIR FOCUS WAS ON THIS SCHOOL.
THEY FOUND THAT FOUR WEAPONS
WERE FOUND AT THE SCHOOL, THREE
FOUND IN THE CLASSROOM A SHOTGUN
WAS FOUND IN LANZA'S CAR THAT
WAS PARKED OUTSIDE THE SCHOOL.
WE ALSO LEARNED THAT LANZA
MOSTLY USED A SEMIAUTOMATIC
WEAPON CALLED A BUSHMASTER
INSIDE THE SCHOOL TO KILL THOSE
26 PEOPLE INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
HE HAD, AS YOU SAID, HE SHOT
DOZENS OF BULLETS AND HE HAD
HUNDREDS OF UNUSED AMMUNITION AS
WELL, HUNDREDS OF BULLETS.
SO IT WAS IT IS NOT CLEAR WHY
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER CAME OUT
YESTERDAY AND EXPLAINED HOW ADAM
LANZA SHOT THOSE 26 PEOPLE
MULTIPLE TIMES, SOME OF THEM, HE
SHOT, SAID THE MEDICAL EXAMINER,
THREE TO 11 TIMES.
IT'S CLEAR THAT LANZA CARRYING
THAT MUCH AMMUNITION ON HIM WAS
LOOKING TO CAUSE THE MOST
DESTRUCTION AND DEATH.
WOLF?
>> WHAT A HORRIFIC, HORRIFIC
CRIME.
ALISON, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
A HUGE CHALLENGE FOR SO MANY
FAMILIES.
BRING IN OUR CHIEF MEDICAL
CORRESPONDENT, DR. SANJAY GUPTA,
HERE WITH US NOW.
POSTTRAUMATIC STRESS DISORDER,
THAT IS GOING TO BE A HUGE
PROBLEM?
>> IT IS.
WE ARE USED TO TALKING ABOUT
THIS IN THE CONTEXT OVER ADULTS
BUT IT CAN HAPPEN IN CHILDREN
AND IT CAN HAPPEN QUICKLY.
I THINK THAT'S TWO THINGS PEOPLE
DON'T ALWAYS REALIZE, HOW THE
CHILDREN BEHAVE NOW, HOW A LOT
OF THESE THINGS ARE IMPLEMENTED
THAT YOU'VE BEEN TALKING ABOUT
WITH PEOPLE OVER THE LAST COUPLE
OF DAYS, IS GOING TO MAKE A BIG
DIFFERENCE, IF CERTAIN
CONVERSATIONS ARE HAD, IF
SPECIAL CARE IS TAKEN TO MAKE
SURE THAT CHILDREN ARE SLEEPING
WELL, FOR EXAMPLE, THEY ARE
GOING TO BE ABLE TO COPE MUCH
BETTER IN THE LONG RUNS, YOU CAN
PREDICT, YOU KNOW, CERTAIN
LIKELIHOOD OF SUCCESS IN TERMS
OF THAT COPING BY WHAT'S
HAPPENING THE NEXT FEW DAYS.
>> WE THINK OF POSTTRAUMATIC
STRESS DISORDER, TROOPS COMING
HOME FROM AFGHANISTAN OR IRAQ.
THIS IS OBVIOUSLY VERY DIFFERENT
FROM THAT.
WHAT ARE THE SYMPTOMS WHAT
SHOULD WE BE LOOKING FORWARD TO?
THIS IS A VERY SERIOUS ILLNESS?
>> ADULTS, YOU THINK ABOUT
THINGS LIKE HYPER VIGILANCE,
DIFFICULTY SLEEPING, ALMOST
HASTY REACTION.
IN CHILDREN, CAN BE VERY
DIFFERENT.
SOMETIMES DON'T VERBALIZE IT
HARD LATE ALL, CHANGES IN HOW
THEY PLAY.
THEY MAY, IN FACT, START PLAYING
TOY GUNS OR SOMETHING LIKE THAT
IF THEY DIDN'T BEFORE.
THEY CAN HAVE REGRESSION.
SO, A 6-YEAR-OLD CAN START
ACTING LIKE A YOUNGER CHILD, FOR
EXAMPLE.
AND AGAIN, JUST PAYING ATTENTION
TO THOSE THINGS AND NOT SORT OF
GLOSSING OVER, OBVIOUSLY DON'T
WANT TO PROVIDE GRAPHIC DETAILS,
MAKE SURE YOU ARE HAVING
CONVERSATIONS, KID GOES BACK
TOLE SCHOOL, DON'T KNOW ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED YET, THEY WILL BY
TOMORROW.
>> THEY WILL IF THEIR PARENTS
DIDN'T TELL THEM, TEACHERS MIGHT
TELL THEM OR CLASSMATES.
>> SOCIAL MEDIA.
THEY WILL HEAR ABOUT.
IT IS AN JAY IS GOING TO BE WITH
US THROUGHOUT THE NIGHT.
WE ARE AWAITING THE PRESIDENT OF
THE UNITED STATES.
HE IS COMING HERE TO NEWTOWN TO
BRING SOME COMFORT TO THE
FAMILIES, THE FIRST RESPONDERS,
ALSO, HE WILL PARTICIPATE IN THE
INTERFAITH VIGIL THAT WILL BE
TAKING PLACE HERE IN
CONNECTICUT.
OUR COVERAGE CONTINUES RIGHT
AFTER THIS.
ñ?
>>> WELCOME BACK TO OUR TOPPING
COVERAGE.
I'M OUTSIDE THE HIGH SCHOOL HERE
INTO NEWTOWN, WHERE PRESIDENT
OBAMA WILL BE ATTENDING AND
SPEAKING AT THE INTERFAITH
SERVICE THAT'S GOING TO TAKE
PLACE STARTING AROUND 7:00
EASTERN TIME TONIGHT.
YOU CAN SEE CARS ARE LINED UP AS
PEOPLE ARE TRYING TO GET IN,
PEOPLE FROM THE COMMUNITY ARE
ALLOWED TO GO, OBVIOUSLY, FAMILY
MEMBERS YOU ANYBODY WHO HAS KIDS
AT THE SCHOOL.
POLICE ARE CHECKING AS PEOPLE GO
IN.
THERE IS A MAKESHIFT MEMORIAL
HERE AROUND A LOT OF FOLKS HAVE
LINED UP, EVEN THOUGH IT IS AN
HOUR OR MORE AWAY, HAVE LINED TO
GO THROUGH METAL DETECTORS IN
ORDER TO GET INTO THE HIGH
SCHOOL SO THEY CAN TAKE PART IN
THIS PRAYER.
PRAYER SERVICE, THIS INTERFAITH
SERVICE.
WE, OF COURSE, ARE GOING TO
BRING THAT TO YOU LIVE THERE ARE
POOL CAMERAS INSIDE, ALL THAT
WILL BE BROADCAST ON CNN SO YOU
CAN WATCH ALONG WHEREVER YOU ARE
AROUND THE UNITED STATES OR
AROUND THE WORLD.
DONLEMON IS HERE IN NEWTOWN.
YOU SPENT TIME HERE THE PAST
COUPLE OF DAYS AS WELL, HOW
PEOPLE ARE GATHERING TOGETHER,
SOMETIMES COMPLETE STRANGERS
COME UP TO YOU AND START
TALKING, TO ME OR JUST ONE
ANOTHER AND DO IT ON STREET
CORNERS OR IN CHURCHES WHICH
HAVE BEEN OPEN AROUND THE CLOCK.
BUT PEOPLE JUST KIND OF WANT TO
SHARE THEIR GRIEF AND SHARE
THEIR EXPERIENCE AS AND THEIR
THOUGHTS AND WHAT'S GOING ON
HERE.
>> THE TWO WORDS ARE USEFUL AND
HELPLESS, PEOPLE WANT TO
CONTRIBUTE AND FEEL USEFUL.
I'M SEEING THIS MAKESHIFT
MEMORIAL, WHEN I GOT HERE JUST
KBRED, THESE WERE FILLED WITH
CANDLES AND 26 OF THESE, STARTED
JUST AS THAT, PEOPLE -- ONE
PERSON BRINGING THEM OVER AND
THEN I'M GOING TO SHOW YOU HOW
BIG IT HAS BROWN BUT LEAVING
CARDS HERE, LIKE TO NEWTOWN,
HOUR THOUGHTS AND PRAYERS WITH
YOU.
CHRISTMAS TREES HERE NOW, DID
BEARS, YOU CAN SEE PEOPLE
DROPPING CANDLES OFF AND
LIGHTING THEM.
SOME GO OUT, THEY MAKE SURE THEY
KEEP THEM LATE, THEY LIGHT THEM
UP AGAIN.
BEHIND US HERE, THERE IS A CREEK
THAT RUNS TO MY RIGHT HERE, LOOK
AT THE TEDDY BEARS PEOPLE HAVE
BROUGHT.
THEY BRING THE NUMBER OF
VICTIMS, THEY BRING 26 OF
EVERYTHING TO PAY TRIBUTE TO THE
PEOPLE, ALL AROUND HERE, THIS
HAS GROWN IN A MATTER OF 24
HOURS THIS IS UNBELIEVABLY.
I SAY EXPONENTIALLY, IT HAS
GROWN, BRINGING FLOWERS, TEDDY
BEARS, LOOK, A LEGOS SET THAT
PEOPLE BRING AND REALLY, THEY
ARE BRINGING TOYS, I WOULD
IMAGINE THAT THIS IS SORT OF
THEIR IDEA OF GIVING IN THE
CHRISTMAS SPIRIT, TRYING TO GIVE
BACK TO THE PEOPLE HERE TO MAKE
SURE THESE KIDS IN HEAVEN HAVE
SOME TOYS HERE.
I'M GOING TO GO TO TALK TO SOME
OF THE PEOPLE.
YOU HAVE BEEN TALKING ABOUT
PEOPLE COMING UP TO US AND HAVE
BEEN COMING UP TO US AS WELL,
THESE GUYS BEING INTERVIEWED BY
MOTHER MEDIA ORGANIZATION,
DOREY, GET IN ON THIS SIDE, YOU
ARE FROM WATERBURY AND IS YOUR
FIANCE, RICH?
WHO IS THIS LITTLE --
>> OUR GRANDDAUGHTER, LILY.
>> SHE IS GORGEOUS.
>> THANK YOU.
>> YOU BROUGHT THIS CHRISTMAS
TREE, RIGHT?
>> WE DID.
WE KEPT THINKING OF TRYING TO DO
SOMETHING AND RICH CAME UP WITH
THE IDEA OF BRINGING A TREE.
>> YEAH.
>> UM, WE WENT AND PICKED UP
SOME ORNAMENTS AND ADDED SOME
BATTERY OPERATED LIGHTS TO THEM
SO THEY COULD FLICKER AROUND
SHAPE.
WE PUT ALL THE NAMES OF THE 20
CHILDREN AND THE SIX TEACHERS ON
THE TREE SO THEY ARE ALL
REPRESENTED THERE.
WE WANT UP FURTHERER AND CAME
BACK DOWN, WE NOTICED PEOPLE
HAVE ADDED MORE STUFF TO THE
TREE AND WE THINK THAT'S GREAT.
I'M A SCHOOL TEACHER IN
WATERBURY.
>> SO, WHEN YOU LOOK AT YOUR
GRAND BABY, OBVIOUSLY, YOU HAVE
KIDS THE ABLE OF THESE KIDS,
WHAT RUNS THROUGH YOUR HEAD YOU
SENT THEM TO SCHOOL EVERY DAY,
I'M SURE AND RESTED IN THE FACT
THEY WOULD BE SAFE.
>> ANYBODY WHO SENDS THEIR KIDS
TO SCHOOL WANTS TO THINK THAT
THAT'S SAFE PLACE FOR THEM.
AS A SCHOOL TEACHER, I WANT TO
SAY I CAN KEEP THEM SAFE BUT
AFTER THIS INCIDENT, IT IS A
VERY HARD THING TO COMMIT TO A
PARENT.
>> RICH, I HAVE BEEN WATCHING
THESE BIG -- AS I SAY, LUG OF
GUYS, BIG MANUALLY MEN, BREAKING
DOWN EVERY TIME I TRY TO TALK TO
THEM, THEY CAN'T GET A WORD OUT
WITHOUT TEARING UP.
>> I'M SPEECHLESS.
MY EMOTIONS ARE RUNNING REALLY
DEEP.
I'M HERE WITH MY CHILDREN, MY
MOM.
THERE'S FOUR GENERATIONS OF US
HERE THIS EVENING.
AND I'M JUST BESIDE MYSELF.
WE ARE HERE TO SHOW SUPPORT TO,
FIRST AND FOREMOST, THE
FAMILIES.
THE LITTLE BABIES.
I CAN'T LET GO OF MY
GRANDDAUGHTER HERE.
I'M JUST -- I'M BESIDE MYSELF.
>> WE KNOW.
>> I'M CERTAINLY HERE TO SUPPORT
THE COMMUNITY.
ALSO, SUPPORT OUR NATION.
WE ARE A NATION IN MOURNING
RIGHT NOW.
>> I WANT TO GET TO THIS TREE
YOU BROUGHT.
THIS IS YOUR ENTIRE FAMILY
THAT'S HERE, RIGHT?
THESE GUYS ARE WITH YOU, ALL OF
THESE FOLKS THAT IS YOUR FAMILY.
WOULD YOU COME OVER HERE AND
TELL US ABOUT THIS TREE, WHAT
YOU DID.
YOU SAID THESE ARE THE NAMES OF
WHAT?
>> THE NAMES OF ALL THE
CHILDREN, WE PUT THEM ON THE
SNOW FLANLGS AND ADDED THE
BATTERY-OPERATED LIGHTS, RICH
DID THE LIGHTING, HE IS AN
ELECTRICIAN BY TRADE.
WE ADDED THE STAR AND WANTED
SOMETHING THAT WOULD BE
REPRESENTING EVERYONE SO WE DID
THE ANGELS ALWAYS WITH THE
CHILDREN WATCHING OVER THEM.
WE KNOW THAT THEY ARE UP THERE
BEING GUIDED AND SAVED JUST LIKE
THE TEACHERS TRIED TO DO HERE
THAT DAY.
>> I SEE THERE ARE TOYS AND
TEDDY BEARS.
I SAID MY THINKING IS MAKING
SURE, FOLKS ARE MAKING SURE THE
KIDS HAVE SOME TOYS FOR
CHRISTMAS UP IN HEAVEN.
>> YES, AND WE HAVE ALREADY SEEN
THOUSANDS OF BAGS THAT THEY HAVE
TOLD US ABOUT THAT HAVE ALREADY
LEFT THE AREA OF TOYS AND THINGS
THAT WERE REPRESENTED HERE THAT
HAVE BEEN -- BEING DONATED TO
LOCAL HOSPITALS AND THINGS LIKE
THAT THE SUPPORT JUST KEEPS
COMING.
>> WHAT IS YOUR NAME, SIR?
>> JONATHAN.
>> HOW ARE YOU DOING, JONATHAN?
>> COULD BE BETTER.
>> WHY ARE YOU HERE?
>> TO SHOW MY SUPPORT AND SHOW
THAT I CARE AND, YOU KNOW
EXLOVE.
YOU KNOW, THAT'S WHAT WE NEED
RIGHT NOW, LOVE, FAITH AND HOPE
IN THE COMMUNITY.
AND AS A WHOLE, YOU KNOW?
THE NATION AS A WHOLE.
WE NEED TO GET TOGETHER AND PRAY
AND JUST DO WHATEVER IT IS
POSSIBLE WE CAN TO SHOW OUR
SUPPORT TO THE FAMILIES OF THE
VICTIMS.
>> THANK YOU.
WE THANK YOU FOR YOUR SUPPORT.
WE ARE GOING TO GET AROUND HERE
AND TALK TO THESE FOLKS AS WELL,
IF YOU WILL LET US.
YOU BROUGHT -- YOU ARE FROM
WESTBURY AS WELL?
>> I'M FROM WATER TOWN,
ACTUALLY.
>> WATER TOWN?
WHAT IS YOUR NAME?
>> GABRIEL MADIGAN.
>> WHO ARE THESE?
>> MY SON DEREK, ZACHARY AND A
FRIEND, CALEB.
>> HOW OLD ARE YOUR KIDS?
>> 12, 6 AND 4 AND COLIN IS 7.
>> AROUND THE SAME AGE AS THE
KIDS.
>> YEAH EARTHQUAKE IT'S
HEARTBREAKING TO THINK THAT THIS
COULD HAPPEN.
YOU ALWAYS THINK IT'S GONNA
HAPPEN SOMEWHERE ELSE, NOT HERE.
>> YOU SEND YOUR KIDS OFF TO
SCHOOL.
WE THINK OF SCHOOLS, CHURCHES,
YOU KNOW, SANCTUARY.
>> A SAFE PLACE.
A SAFE PLACE.
I REMEMBER BEING AT WORK, I WORK
IN FAIRFIELD, AND HEARING WHAT
WAS GOING ON.
AND FEELING SO HELPLESS BECAUSE
WE DIDN'T KNOW IT WAS -- AND TO
THINK THAT I COULD GO HOME AND
HUG MY KIDS AND SO MANY PARENTS
OUT THERE CAN'T.
IT'S HEARTBREAKING.
>> YES, YOU WERE SAYING THAT I
WAS THINKING THE SAME THING,
IT'S HEARTBREAKING.
>> YES, IT IS.
OH, YES, ABSOLUTELY.
>> WHERE ARE YOU FROM?
>> I'M FROM WATER BURRRY.
>> WHAT IS YOUR NAME?
>> ANGELA.
>> WHY DID YOU COME OUT HERE ON
A RAINY NIGHT?
>> IT KIND OF HITS HOME BECAUSE
I HAVE CHILDREN WITHIN THE SAME
AGES AND IT'S JUST -- IT'S JUST
HEARTBREAKING.
I CAN'T FATHOM SOMEBODY CAN DO
SUCH A HORRIBLE THING.
>> I CAN'T BELIEVE ALL THESE
GUYS.
WALK AROUND HERE IF YOU CAN GET
THROUGH, SHOW YOU MORE OF THE
MEMORIAL IF YOU CAN COME AROUND
THIS WAY AND TALK TO MORE OF
THESE PEOPLE.
WE WANT TO YOU SEE EXACTLY
WHAT'S GOING ON.
THIS IS THE FRONT OF THE
MEMORIAL, THEY BLOCKED THE
SCHOOL, THE ROAD TO THE SCHOOL
OFF PEOPLE ARE STREAMING, YOU
SEE FAITH, HOPE, LOVE, YOU SEE
UP HERE, GOD BLESS CINDY HOOK.
THE CANDLES, THE TOYS, THE
FLOWERS, THE STUFFED ANIMALS,
PEOPLE COMING OUT HERE ON A
RAINY NIGHT SO THEY CAN FEEL, AS
I SAID IN THE BEGINNING OF THIS,
FEEL THAT THEY ARE USEFUL HERE
AND THAT THEY ARE NOT HELPLESS,
ANDERSON.
>> I KNOW YOU HAVE HAD THIS AS
WELL, PEOPLE COME UP AND THEY
ARE THANKFUL THAT WE ARE TRYING
TO FOCUS ON THE VICTIMS IN ALL
OF THIS NOT TALK ABOUT -- NOT
NAME THE SHOOTER BY NAME
CONSTANTLY OF AND OVER AGAIN.
ALSO, PEOPLE HAVE SAID TO ME A
NUMBER OF TIMES, YOU KNOW, WE
DON'T WANT OUR TOWN TO BE KNOWN
FOR THIS WE ARE MUCH MORE THAN A
POINT, I'M SURE YOU HAVE HEARD
THAT PEOPLE SPECIFICALLY COME UP
TO ME AND LET PEOPLE KNOW, WE
ARE MORE THAN THIS, JUST SEEING
THIS MEMORIAL THAT YOU'RE AT
NOW, THAT'S WHAT NEWTOWN IS,
THOSE PEOPLE WHO HAVE COME,
THAT'S WHAT THIS TOWN IS ALL
ABOUT, DON.
>> CAN I SAY SOMETHING TO YOU,
ANDERSON?
JUST -- I INTERVIEWED SOMEONE
AND I SAID, THEY SAID WHAT'S --
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
WHY I DO HEAR THE SIGH REMEMBER.
THE PRESIDENT WASN'T HERE YET,
IT WAS SOMETHING ELSE.
AND I SAID THIS TOWN HAS
CHANGED, HASN'T IT?
YEAH EARTHQUAKE IT'S LIKE BEING
AT A CIRCUS, QUITE FRANKLY, BUT
NOBODY IS HAVING FUN.
THIS HAS GONE FROM A BUCOLIC,
IDEAL TOWN, OVERNIGHT TO POLICE
CARS, EMERGENCY VEHICLES, THE
MEDIA.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
THIS IS NOT WHAT THEY WANT THEIR
TOWN TO BE KNOWN FOR.
THEY WANT IT TO BE KNOWN FOR THE
TYPE OF TOWN, YOU KNOW, NEW
ENGLAND TOWN THAT LOOKS LIKE A
POSTCARD.
IT LOOKS LIKE A CHRISTMAS
VILLAGE, ANDERSON, LIKE ONE OF
THOSE LITTLE TRAIN THINGS WITH A
CHRISTMAS VILLAGE, THAT'S WHAT
IT LOOKS LIKE.
>> WE ARE GOING TO GO BACK TO
WOLF BLITZER STANDING BY WITH
SANJAY GUPTA.
WAITING ARRIVAL OF PRESIDENT
OBAMA.
AS YOU KNOW, HE WILL BE AT THE
HIGH SCHOOL FOR THIS
INTERSERVICE VIGIL, OF COURSE
THIS SERVICE THAT WE ARE GOING
TO BE BROADCASTING, PROBABLY
GOING TO LAST TWO HOURS OR SO,
NOT SURE THE EXACT LENGTH, THERE
WILL BE A NUMBER OF SPEAKERS
FROM THE COMMUNITY, PRESIDENT
OBAMA AS WELL, ALL OF THAT, OF
COURSE, WILL BE BROADCAST LIVE,
WOLF.
>> YEAH, WE ARE GOING TO HAVE
EXTENSIVE COVERAGE, NON-STOP
COVERAGE OF THE ACTUAL
INTERFAITH VIGIL, SANJAY GUPTA
IS WATCHING ALL OF THIS UNFOLD.
WHEN YOU SEE THESE OTHER
PARENTS, THEY COME WITH THEIR
LITTLE KIDS, BRING LITTLE TOYS,
LITTLE CHRISTMAS TREES OR
WHATEVER, WHAT DOES THIS DO?
I MEAN, IT JUST -- IT'S JUST
SUCH A POWERFUL IMAGE, PEOPLE
WANT TO DO SOMETHING, THEY DON'T
KNOW WHAT TO DO THEY COME HERE.
COUNTRY MOVE AROUND THIS TOWN
RIGHT NOW, YOU CERTAINLY CAN'T
DRIVE AROUND T.
>> THAT SCENE WITH DON LEMON,
JUST UP AND DOWN THESE STREETS,
YOU AND I HAVE BEEN WALKING
AROUND, YOU SEE THAT EVERYWHERE,
LAST NIGHT IN BETWEEN TALKING TO
YOU, I WENT TO GRAB A CUP OF
COFFEE, AND A WOMAN CAME OVER TO
ME, I HAD NEVER MET HER BEFORE
AND JUST GAVE ME A HUG.
I THINK IT'S THERAPEUTIC.
IT'S CATHARTIC, TO SOME HE
EXTENT.
THE WHOLE IDEA THAT YOU DO
SOMETHING, WHATEVER IT MAY BE,
AND THAT SOMEHOW YOU FEEL
BETTER, MENTALLY, PHYSICALLY, BY
ACTUALLY GOING OUT AND DOING
SOMETHING, I THINK IT'S
EMPOWERING IN SOME WAY, TAKES
AWAY THOSE FEELINGS OF ISOLATION
WE HAVE BEEN TALKING ABOUT AND
PEOPLE GATHERING TOGETHER, I
THINK, I THINK THIS IS OUR
DEFAULT POSITION, WOLF, I THINK
IF YOU LOOK AT THE HUMAN SPIRIT
THIS IS THE DEFAULT POSITION,
WHO WE ARE NORMALLY, WE RARELY
GET AN OPPORTUNITY TO EXPRESS
IT.
SOMETIMES A TRAGEDY LIKE THIS
BRINGS IT OUT.
I THINK IT'S JUST PART OF WHO WE
ARE AND WE ARE SEEING THIS SORT
OF THING PLAY OUT, NOT JUST HERE
IN NEWTOWN, BUT I THINK IN MANY
PRAISES AROUND THE COUNTRY.
I WAS TALKING TO MY WIFE AND SHE
WAS SWAG HER OWN FRIENDS LAST
NIGHT, THEY GOT TOGETHER AND
WERE TALKING A LOT ABOUT THIS
AND I THINK REALLY TRYING TO
COMFORT EACH OTHER AND I THINK
IT'S EMPOWERING AND AGAIN, VERY
THERAPEUTIC FOR THEM.
>> SO MANY PEOPLE ARE STAYING IS
SO PAINFUL TO WATCH BUT THEY
WANT TO WATCH, AT THE SAME TIME.
THEY DON'T WANT TO ESCAPE.
THEY DON'T WANT TO RUNAWAY FROM
THIS, BECAUSE THIS IS NOT A
STORY, A MOVIE, THIS IS REAL
LIFE, WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
>> I THINK, JUST FROM A MEDIA
PERSPECTIVE, PEOPLE COMING UP TO
US WANTING TO TALK.
I THINK VERY NATURAL FOR US NOT
TO WANT TO INFRINGE.
WE WOULDN'T WANT TO TO HAVE
PEOPLE INFRINGING ON OUR FRIENDS
SOMETHING SO TRAGIC HAPPENED.
I THINK MAYBE IT'S TO HONOR THE
PEOPLE AROUND HERE.
MAYBE IT'S TO HONOR THE VICTIMS
HERE IN NEWTOWN.
MAYBE IT'S JUST TO, AGAIN, HAVE
THAT FEELING OF BEING EMPOWERED,
DOING SOMETHING.
I ABSOLUTELY AGREE WITH YOU.
>> WE ARE STANDING BY, THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
IS -- WILL BE HERE FOR THIS
INTERFAITH VIGIL.
YESTERDAY, I HAD A CHANCE TO
SPEAK WITH A MINISTER AND RABBI
LEADING THIS VIGIL.
THAT IS COMING UP.
THE SPECIAL COVERAGE OF THE
VIGIL WILL BEGIN AS SOON AS THE
PRESIDENT IS HERE.
ALSO, MUCH MORE OF THE AFTERMATH
OF THIS HORRENDOUS SHOOTING,
RIGHT AFTER THIS.
SPEAK WITH A MINISTER AND RABBI
LEADING THIS VIGIL.
Ñe
>>> ALL 20 OF THE SLAIN CHILDREN
IN THE CONNECTICUT SHOOTING, 6
OR 7 YEARS OLD.
IT'S SO SHOCKING TO HEAR THOSE
AGES, 6 OR 7.
YOUNG VICTIMS OF A SENSELESS,
HORRIBLE ATTACK.
JOINING ME RIGHT NOW FROM
SEATTLE IS VICTORIA HALLER.
HER NEPHEW, 6-YEAR-OLD NOAH
POZNER, WAS KILLED IN THE
SHOOTING.
I'M SO SORRY FOR YOUR LOSS.
HOW ARE YOU, HOW IS YOUR FAMILY
HOLDING UP?
>> THANK YOU, ANDERSON.
WE ARE ALL COMPLETELY SHATTERED.
IT'S BEEN VERY, VERY ROUGH FEW
DAYS.
NOBODY'S GETTING VERY MUCH
SLEEP.
WE ARE HOLDING TOGETHER AS BEST
WE CAN BUT YOU NEVER, EVER THINK
SOMETHING LIKE THIS CAN CAN
HAPPEN TO YOUR FAMILY.
>> TELL US ABOUT NOAH WHAT KIND
OF A BOY WAS HE?
>> NOAH WAS EXTREMELY LIVELY, HE
WAS REALLY THE LIGHT OF THE
ROOM.
YOU KNOW, HE HAD A HUGE HEART
AND HE WAS SO MUCH FUN.
A LITTLE BIT RAM BURBUNCTIOUS, D
PLAYING WITH HIS COUSINS, LOVED
HIS TWIN MOST OF ALL AND ALWAYS
SAID THAT THEY WERE BEST
FRIENDS.
THOSE BIG BLUE EYES, A GORGEOUS,
GORGEOUS BOY.
HE COULD GET WHAT HE WANTED JUST
BY BATTING THOSE LONG EYELASHES
AND LOOK IT'S WITH YOU THOSE BIG
BLUE EYES, YOU REALLY COULDN'T
SAY NO TO HIM.
>> NOAH HAS TWO STARS THIS
ATTENDED THE SAME SCHOOL,
THANKFULLY YOU BOTH GIRLS
SURVIVED THE ATTACK AND I KNOW
ONE WAS DESCRIBED AS HIS BEST
FRIEND, HIS TWIN SISTER, ARIAL.
>> YES.
>> HAVE THEY BEEN TOLD?
DO THEY KNOW WHAT HAPPENED?
>> THEY DON'T KNOW THE WAY IN
WHICH NOAH PASSED AWAY, BUT
OBVIOUSLY, THEY WERE THERE
DURING THE WHOLE EVENT AND WERE
LED OUT, IT'S NOT SOMETHING
THAT, YOU KNOW, SHE JUST TURNED
SI
SIX, ARIEL JUST TURNED 6.
HOW DO YOU TELL THEM THAT IS HOW
THEIR BROTHER DIED?
IT IS THE UNTHINKABLE REALLY.
>> I KNOW OFF SON NOAH'S AGE.
SO MANY PARENTS HERE AND AROUND
THE WORLD ARE TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT HOW TO TALK TO THEIR KIDS
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED.
I'M WONDERING JUST AS A PARENT,
HOW DO YOU TALK TO YOUR SON
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED?
>> IT WAS EMOTION A.M. AND TE  -
TEAR-FILLED AND WE NEEDED TO DO
IT RIGHT AWAY.
WE IMMEDIATELY CALLED A GRIEF
COUNSELOR HERE IN SEATTLE TO GET
ADVICE BECAUSE IT IS NOTHING WE
EVER HAD TO DEAL WITH BEFORE.
HIS ADVICE WAS TO TELL THEM
ENOUGH DETAILS SO THEY DON'T
FILL IN THE BLANKS THEMSELVES
BECAUSE CHILDREN HAVE VERY
ACTIVE IMAGINATIONS AND THEY
WILL THINK THE WORST.
TELL THEM WHAT HAPPENED.
WE TOLD THEM THAT A BAD PERSON
CAME AND SHOT HIS COUSIN AND
THAT HE HAD PASSED AWAY AND OUR
SON ASKED WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
IT MEANS HE DIED.
AND HE, YOU KNOW, WAS GOING TO
TRY AND IT IS JUST -- I THINK
INCOMPREHENSIBLE FOR A BOY
THAT'S NOT EVEN 6 YET.
NOAH AND ARIEL AND MY SON,
ETHAN, SIX WEEKS APART, THEY
WERE SO CLOSE AND THEY WERE JUST
BUDDIES AND, YOU KNOW, IT'S SO
SO PAINFUL KNOWING THAT NOW, MY
SON IS GONNA GROW UP WITHOUT HIS
MALE COUSIN BUDDY, YOU KNOW?
THAT WAS HIS -- THAT WAS HIS
GUY.
AND TALKING TO HIM PRIMARILY ON
FRIDAY AND THROUGHOUT THE
WEEKEND, WHEN I'M EMOTIONAL,
IT'S HARD TO KEEP IT TOGETHER,
EVEN THOUGH I HAVE TO AT THE
MOMENT BECAUSE I'M ONLY ONE AT
HOME WITH MY TWO KIDS.
MY HUSBAND IS WITH HIS SISTER
AND MY MOTHER-IN-LAW AND TAKING
CARE OF EVERYTHING OUT THERE.
I JUST TELL THEM I'M SAD AND
THAT THE FAMILY'S SAD AND THAT I
LOVE HIM VERY MUCH AND I'M SO
GLAD THAT HE'S MY BABY AND, YOU
KNOW EXTHERE A
KNOW, THERE'S NOT MUCH YOU CAN
DO REALLY.
>> YEAH.
WHAT MORE CAN WE DO?
VICTORIA, I APPRECIATE YOU
TALKING TO US AND PLEASE PASS
ALONG OUR CONDOLENCES AND OUR
THOUGHTS AND OUR PRAYERS AND --
TO YOUR FAMILY.
I CAN'T IMAGINE --
>> THANK YOU.
I WILL.
>> WHAT THEY ARE GOING THROUGH.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> THANK YOU, ANDERSON.
>> I WISH YOU STRENGTH IN THE
DIFFICULT DAYS AHEAD.
THANK YOU, VICTORIA.
WE WILL BE RIGHT BACK.
>>> OPENER MY SHOULDER THERE IS
A MAKESHIFT PEOPLE NOR Y'ALL BY
THE POLICE LIGHTS BEHIND ME,
PEOPLE HAVE GATHERED TO BRING
FLOWERS AND TEDDY BEARS AND
REMEMBRANCES FOR ALL THE LIVES
THAT HAVE BEEN LOST.
WE, OF COURSE, ARE GOING TO BE
BRINGING YOU THAT INTERFAITH
SERVICE LIVE, THERE WILL BE POOL
CAMERAS INSIDE, BRING THAT TO
YOU AS IT HAPPENS.
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT IS
OBVIOUSLY HOME TO ONE OF THE
MOST HORRIFIC TRAGEDIES EVER TO
OCCUR IN THE UNITED STATES, BUT
THE RESIDENTS HERE DON'T WANT
THAT TO BE THE LEGACY.
A GROUP OF RESIDENTS CALLED
NEWTOWN UNITED ARE COMING
TOGETHER TO DISCUSS THE ISSUES
AT HAND, GUN CONTROL, MENTAL
HEALTH AMONG THEM, TRYING TO GET
POLITICAL LEADERS TO ACT AND
PREVENT ANYTHING LIKE THIS
HAPPENING ANY PLACE ELSE.
THE GROUP INVITED KYUNG LAH TO
ATTEND THAT MEETING.
SHE JOINS US NOW.
>> Reporter: WE'RE GOING TO
START TO HEAR THE GRIEF IN THIS
SERVICE, THE ENTIRE TOWN
MOURNING.
WHEN THIS GROUP OF RESIDENTS
WANT THE PRESIDENT TO HEAR IS
THEY DO NOT WANT THIS TO
CONTINUE.
THEY WERE INVITED INTO THIS
INTIMATE MEETING, THIS GROUP,
WHERE THEY ALL KNOW A CHILD WHO
DIED IN THAT CLASSROOM.
THEY ARE HEARTBROKEN, BUT THEY
ARE ALSO FRUSTRATED AND ANGRY,
AND THEY WANT TO DO SOMETHING.
SO WHAT THEY ARE SAYING THAT,
WHILE THE POLITICIANS ARE
LISTENING, WHILE THE NATIONAL
MEDIA IS HERE, THEY WANT PEOPLE
TO PAY ATTENTION TO THE
DIFFICULT ISSUES.
THE DIFFICULT ISSUES WE OFTEN
IGNORE, GUN CONTROL, HOW TO BE
TAKING CARE OF ONE ANOTHER, AND
ALSO MENTAL ILLNESS.
HERE'S WHAT WE HEARD.
>> WE LIVE IN AN INCREASINGLY
VOYEURISTIC SOCIETY THAT MAKES
PEOPLE FEEL DISTANT FROM OTHER
PEOPLE, AND THAT'S HOW THEY CAN
SHOOT CHILDREN.
>> IN THE POLITICAL SYSTEM, WE
CAN'T FIND COMMON GROUND TO TALK
ABOUT ANYTHING THESE DAYS.
IF THIS IS A TRIGGER POINT AND A
TIPPING POINT FOR US AND OUR
ELECTED OFFICIALS TO ACTUALLY
START TALKING TO EACH OTHER IN A
WAY THAT'S RESPECTFUL AND
RESULTS IN REAL CHANGE, THAT
WOULD BE HUGE.
>> Reporter: AND THE PEOPLE IN
THIS ROOM SAY THEY DO REPRESENT
A LOT OF PEOPLE WHO ARE MUCH
WAING AT HOME, PEOPLE ARE
FRUSTRATED THAT WE'RE NOT
TACKLING THESE ISSUES, AND
WITHOUT TACKLING THEM, WITHOUT
DISCUSSING THEM, AND WITHOUT THE
POLITICAL ACTION AT THE VERY
TOP, ANDERSON, THEY SAY THAT
THIS GRIEVING WILL NOT JUST END
AT THIS TOWN.
ANDERSON?
>> AS WE WAIT FOR THE MEMORIAL
SERVICE TO BEGIN, WHICH IS
SUPPOSED TO OCCUR AT THE 7:00
HOUR.
IT'S SUPPOSED TO LAST ABOUT TWO
HOURS LONG.
PRESIDENT OBAMA, AMONG MANY
OTHERS, WILL BE SPEAKING.
ALL OF THAT WILL BE BROADCAST
LIVE RIGHT HERE ON CNN, BUT OUR
COVERAGE CONTINUES.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A SHORT
BREAK.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
THERE'S A HEALTH COMPANY THAT
CAN HELP YOU STAY THAT WAY.
WHAT'S HEALTHIER THAN THAT?
HOW THEY'LL LIVE TOMORROW.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
>>> WELCOME BACK TO OUR
CONTINUING COVERAGE.
HORRIBLE EVENTS HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE WAITING FOR THE INTERFAITH
PRAYER SERVICE THAT WILL BEGIN
ONE HOUR FROM NOW.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL BE SPEAKING
WITH MANY OTHERS.
I'M OUTSIDE THE HIGH SCHOOL
HERE, WHERE YOU CAN SEE THE
FLASHING LIGHTS BEHIND ME,
POLICE CARS, A MAKESHIFT
MEMORIAL, AND HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE
HAVE LINED UP IN THE DRIZZLING
RAIN AND THE COLD, WAITING TO
GET INTO THE HIGH SCHOOL TO BE
PART OF THIS SERVICE.
SO MANY PEOPLE IN THIS ENTIRE
COMMUNITY, THEY FEEL A PART OF
THIS, AND THEY WANT TO BE A PART
OF IT, AND THEY WANT THEIR GRIEF
TO BE SHARED, AND THEY WANT TO
SHARE THEIR GRIEF WITH OTHER
PEOPLE.
26 PEOPLE, INCLUDING 20 KIDS,
WERE KILLED IN THAT SCHOOL.
WE ALL KNOW THE DETAILS BY NOW
SO WHAT, BUT WE'RE NOW LEARNING
MORE AND MORE ABOUT EACH OF THE
YOUNG LIVES THAT WERE TAKEN AND
THE TEACHERS AND SCHOOL
ADMINISTRATORS WHOSE LIVE WERE
TAKEN.
SO MANY LIVES TAKEN FAR TOO
SOON.
♪
>> JUST A TRAGIC, TRAGIC
SITUATION FOR THE TEACHERS, THE
PRINCIPALS, AND THOSE ANGELS.
THAT'S ALL I CAN THINK ABOUT IS
THOSE ANGELS.
>> I MEAN, WHEN THINGS HAPPEN TO
YOUR CHILDREN AND TO OTHER
PEOPLE'S CHILDREN, I CAN'T LOOK
AT MY CHILDREN'S FACES NOW
WITHOUT SEEING THE FACES OF
EVERY ONE OF THEIR SCHOOL MATES.