REMEMBER TIPPER GORE WHEN SHE
DEALT WITH THIS ISSUE AND TRIED
TO BRING IT TO THE FOREFRONT BUT
IT'S SORT OF GONE AWAY.
GUN CONTROL IS IMPORTANT.
THERE'S NO DOUBT ABOUT THAT.
MENTAL HEALTH, DEALING WITH THIS
AND TAKING IT OUT OF THE BACK
ROOMS AND DEALING WITH IT AND IF
A LOVED ONE SEES A YOUNG KID WHO
HAS SOME PROBLEMS, NOT JUST
PRETEND THEY DON'T EXIST.
THERE ARE MEDICAL TREATMENTS.
>> ALSO OFTEN TIMES PARENTS
CAN'T REALLY GET HELP UNLESS THE
CHILD CAN BE PROVEN TO BE A
DANGER TO THEMSELVES OR OTHERS.
>> RIGHT.
>> THAT'S OFTEN WAITS UNTIL A
CRIME IS COMMITTED FOR --
>> WE DON'T KNOW ENOUGH ABOUT
THE SHOOTER IN THIS CASE.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT KIND OF
ISSUES THIS INDIVIDUAL MAY OR
MAY NOT HAVE HAD.
WE HAD.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT KIND OF
TREATMENT HE MAY OR MAY NOT HAVE
HAD.
I SUSPECT WE'RE GOING TO LEARN A
LOT MORE.
>> THAT DOES IT FOR US HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
THANK YOU FOR WATCHING.
"EARLY START" BEGINS NEXT.
♪
>>> ON THIS SPECIAL EDITION OF
"EARLY START," A COMMUNITY AND A
NATION IN MOURNING.
>> NEWTOWN, YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
>> THE PRESIDENT, OFFERING WORDS
OF COMFORT AND INSPIRATION, TO
THOSE TRYING TO MAKE SENSE OF A
SENSELESS TRAGEDY.
>> THE FACE OF INDESCRIBABLE
VIOLENCE.
IN THE FACE OF UNCONSCIONABLE
EVIL.
YOU'VE LOOKED OUT OF EACH OTHER.
AND YOU CARED FOR ONE ANOTHER.
AND YOU'VE LOVED ONE ANOTHER.
>> WE'RE REMEMBERING THE
VICTIMS, 20 CHILDREN AND 6
ADULTS.
SOME WHO GAVE THEIR LIVES TO
SAVE OTHERS.
>> SHE WAS TRULY SELFLESS.
SHE WOULD NOT HESITATE TO SAVE
ANYONE ELSE BEFORE HERSELF,
ESPECIALLY CHILDREN.
>> AS MORE DETAILS EMERGE,
PEOPLE IN THE SMALL COMMUNITY
SEARCH FOR STRENGTH TO FACE THE
DIFFICULT DAYS AHEAD.
>> WE WILL MOVE ON.
WE WILL NEVER FORGET.
WE WILL, IN MANY WAYS, BE MADE
STRONGER FOR WHAT HAS
TRANSPIRED.
AND WE WILL GET BETTER.
>>> GOOD MORNING.
AND WELCOME TO THIS SPECIAL
EDITION OF "EARLY START."
>> IT IS 5:00 A.M. IN THE EAST.
WE'RE COMING TO YOU LIVE FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, THIS
MORNING.
IT IS A RAW AND RAINY MORNING
HERE.
GRIEF-STRICKEN NEIGHBORS ARE
HOLDING EACH OTHER TIGHT,
PREPARING FOR THE FIRST FUNERALS
TODAY, IN THE AFTERMATH OF THE
MASSACRE AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> HERE'S THE LATEST.
PRESIDENT OBAMA CAME HERE LAST
NIGHT, OFFERING COMFORT TO THE
INCONSOLABLE IN PRIVATE.
THEN, IN AN INTERFAITH SERVICE,
TELLING THOSE WHO LOST LOVED
ONES, YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
AND PROMISING TO USE ALL OF HIS
POWERS AS PRESIDENT TO STOP
THESE KINDS OF TRAGEDIES.
TODAY, NEWTOWN WILL BEGIN
BURYING ITS DEAD.
FUNERALS FOR JACK PINTO, AND
NOAH POZNER.
>> WE'LL GET TO KNOW MORE ABOUT
ANA MARQUEZ-GREEN.
SHE IS A LITTLE GIRL WHO LIKED
TO SING WHILE HER BROTHER PLAYED
THE PIANO.
WE'LL BRING THE LATEST ON THE
SUSPECTED SHOOTER.
HOW POLICE SAY HE GOT INTO THE
SCHOOL.
AND WHY HE MAY HAVE BEEN
TARGETING IT.
>>> AND ALSO, AN EXCLUSIVE,
HEARTBREAKING, WRENCHING
INTERVIEW, WITH THE SANDY HOOK
PRINCIPAL, DAWN HOCHSPRUNG.
WHAT HER DAUGHTERS WANT YOU TO
KNOW ABOUT THEIR MOTHER.
>> FUNERAL SERVICES THIS
AFTERNOON FOR THE TWO, BEAUTIFUL
LITTLE BOYS.
JACK PINTO, JUST 6 YEARS OLD,
AND NOAH POZNER, JUST TURNED 6
LAST MONTH.
THIS CLOSE-KNIT COMMUNITY IS
BEGINNING TO SAY GOOD-BYE.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
THIS GRIEF-STRICKEN COMMUNITY
NOW HAS THE HEARTBREAKING TASK
OF LAYING THEIR LOVED ONES TO
REST.
LAST NIGHT, PRESIDENT OBAMA
SPOKE TO RESIDENTS HERE IN
NEWTOWN, TO OFFER WORDS OF
COMFORT.
OFFER CONDOLENCES FROM AN ENTIRE
NATION.
SAYING TRAGEDIES LIKE THESE MUST
END.
>> AS A COMMUNITY, YOU'VE
INSPIRED US, NEWTOWN.
IN THE FACE OF INDESCRIBABLE
VIOLENCE, IN THE FACE OF
UNCONSCIONABLE EVIL, YOU'VE
LOOKED OUT FOR EACH OTHER.
YOU'VE CARED FOR ONE ANOTHER.
AND YOU'VE LOVED ONE ANOTHER.
THIS IS HOW NEWTOWN WILL BE
REMEMBERED.
AND WITH TIME AND GOD'S GRACE,
THAT LOVE WILL SEE YOU THROUGH.
>> Reporter: THE PRESIDENT ALSO
MET WITH VICTIMS' FAMILY MEMBERS
AT A VIGIL TO REMEMBER THE LIVES
LOST IN FRIDAY'S TRAGEDY.
TODAY, THE FIRST OF MANY
FUNERALS.
BEING LAID TO REST THIS
AFTERNOON, 6-YEAR-OLD NOAH
POZNER.
HE HAS A TWIN SISTER, WHO FAMILY
MEMBERS SAY DOESN'T KNOW THE
EXACT WAY HER BROTHER DIED.
ALSO BEING LAID TO REST, JACK
PINTO.
HE'S A BIG GIANTS FAN.
CRUZ WROTE A TRIBUTE TO JACK
PINTO ON HIS CLEATS, SAYING JACK
PINTO, MY HERO.
>> THIS IS HARD TO TALK ABOUT.
THE WHOLE CONCEPT OF RETURNING
TO SCHOOL.
I KNOW THERE'S A PLAN FOR SANDY
HOOK KIDS TO RETURN TO SCHOOL.
WHAT ARE THEY?
>> RIGHT NOW, ALL SCHOOLS HERE
IN NEWTOWN WILL BE CLOSED TODAY,
SO THAT STAFF CAN TALK TO
EXPERTS TO SEE HOW BEST TO TALK
TO THEIR STUDENTS, TO HANDLE THE
AFTERMATH OF FRIDAY'S SHOOTING.
TOMORROW, SCHOOL WILL RESUME,
EXCEPT FOR SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
THEY ARE TALKING TO SCHOOLS IN A
NEIGHBORING TOWN TO SEE IF
STUDENTS CAN BE ACCOMMODATED
THERE.
>>> CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE ARE
PAINSTAKINGLY PIECING TOGETHER
THE EVIDENCE FROM FRIDAY'S
MASSACRE.
THEY HAVE POSITIVELY IDENTIFIED
ADAM LANZA AS THE MAN WHO OPENED
FIRE AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AND TOOK HIS OWN LIFE.
WE DON'T KNOW WHY HE TARGETED
THAT SCHOOL AND THE PEOPLE
INSIDE.
GOOD MORNING, ALLISON.
WHAT'S THE LATEST?
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING, JOHN.
ACTUALLY, POLICE HAVE MOVED US
MUCH CLOSER, UP TO THE LANZA
HOME.
IN FACT, IT'S RIGHT OVER MY
SHOULDER HERE.
IT'S A HUGE HOUSE THAT SITS ON A
HILL.
RIGHT NOW, THERE'S A COUPLE OF
POLICE CARS STILL SITTING IN
FRONT OF THIS HOUSE.
AS NEWTOWN CONTINUES TO GRIEVE,
THOUGH, THIS INVESTIGATION
CONTINUES IN EARNEST.
ESPECIALLY ABOUT WHAT THIS
GUNMAN WAS UP TO, THE DAYS AND
THE WEEKS AND THE MONTHS LEADING
UP TO THIS MASSACRE AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY.
INVESTIGATORS SAY THEY HAVE
PROOF THAT THE GUNMAN WAS AT ONE
GUN RANGE.
BUT THEY WON'T SAY WHERE OR
WHEN.
THEY SAY HIS MOTHER, NANCY
LANZA, WHO THE GUNMAN KILLED
BEFORE HE WENT TO THE SCHOOL,
WAS ALSO AS A GUN RANGE.
VISITED A GUN RANGE MULTIPLE
TIMES.
THEY'RE NOT SAYING WHEN OR
WHERE, EITHER.
INVESTIGATORS SAY THEY'VE GOT AN
IMMENSE AMOUNT OF WITNESSES TO
STILL TALK TO, INCLUDING
CHILDREN.
THEY'VE GOT TO INTERVIEW A LOT
OF PEOPLE.
AND THEY SAY THEY'VE GOT WEEKS'
WORTH OF WORK AHEAD OF THEM.
THEY'RE NOT YET READY TO SAY
WHAT THE MOTIVE IS BEHIND THE
SHOOTING.
>> AGAIN, MOTIVE, AS I DISCUSSED
EARLIER, THAT WILL COME AS WE
FINISH THE INVESTIGATION.
WE DIDN'T PIECEMEAL IT.
WE DON'T HAVE A SPECIFIC REASON
TO STAND HERE AND SAY THIS
OCCURRED.
WE WILL.
AND WE ARE SEARCHING DILIGENTLY
AND NONSTOP TO ANSWER THAT
QUESTION.
>> FEDERAL AGENTS CONTINUE
CHASING LEADS.
THEY'RE LOOKING AT AS MANY AS 30
GUN RANGES, HUNDREDS OF GUN
DEALERS IN A 4-COUNTY AREA,
SURROUNDING THE NEWTOWN AREA.
THEY'RE TRYING TO GET ANSWERS AS
TO WHAT THIS GUNMAN WAS UP TO,
BEFORE HE OPENED FIRE INSIDE
THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
JOHN?
>> AS YOU SAY, ALLISON, THERE'S
SO MANY QUESTIONS.
ALISON KOSIK, OUTSIDE THE LANZA
HOUSE HERE.
>>> AND THE GUN CONTROL DEBATE
IS RAGING IN AMERICA.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SAYS WE NEED
MORE MEANINGFUL ACTION TO
PREVENT FUTURE TRAGEDIES.
OPPONENTS OF GUN CONTROL IN
CONGRESS, MAINTAIN THAT
AMERICANS HAVE A RIGHT TO BEAR
ARMS.
BUT SUPPORTERS OF GUN RIGHTS
QUESTION THE RIGHT TO OWN
CERTAIN TYPES OF GUNS.
>> THESE ARE ASSAULT WEAPONS.
YOU DON'T HUNT DEER WITH THESE
TYPES OF THINGS.
I THINK THAT'S THE QUESTION THAT
A LOT OF PEOPLE HAVE TO RESOLVE
IN THEIR OWN MINDS.
WHERE SHOULD THIS LINE GET
DRAWN?
>> A FREE PEOPLE SHOULD BE AN
ARMED PEOPLE.
IT ENSURES AGAINST THE TYRANNY
OF THE GOVERNMENT, IF THEY KNOW
THAT THE BIGGEST ARMY IS THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE.
>> A NUMBER OF GUN CONTROL
MEASURES HAVE BEEN INTRODUCED IN
CONGRESS OVER THE PAST FEW
YEARS.
BUT NOT A SINGLE ONE HAS MADE IT
TO THE FLOOR FOR A VOTE.
SENATOR DIANNE FEINSTEIN OF
CALIFORNIA SAYS SHE PLANS TO
INTRODUCE A BILL NEXT MONTH THAT
PLACES A BAN ON ASSAULT WEAPONS.
>> TODAY IS THE FIRST DAY
STUDENTS ACROSS THE COUNTRY
RETURN TO SCHOOL SINCE THE
MASSACRE IN CONNECTICUT.
AND FROM COAST-TO-COAST, SCHOOL
DISTRICTS ARE EXPECTED TO REVIEW
THEIR SECURITY PLANS TO SATISFY
ANXIOUS PARENTS, STUDENTS,
TEACHERS.
I WAS RECEIVING MEMOS FROM MY
KIDS' SCHOOL ALL WEEKEND.
POLICE DEPARTMENTS AROUND THE
COUNTRY ARE EXPECTED TO INCREASE
PATROLS.
AND MANY DISTRICTS WILL OFFER
ADDITIONAL COUNSELING SERVICES
TO FRIGHTENED STUDENTS.
>>> AND "SATURDAY NIGHT LIVE,"
KNOWN TO TAKE ON THE NEWS WITH
COMEDY, TOOK A DIFFERENT
APPROACH THIS WEEKEND.
>> THE NEW YORK CITY'S
CHILDREN'S CHORUS OPENED THE
SHOW SINGING "SILENT NIGHT."
♪ SILENT NIGHT
HOLY NIGHT ♪
♪ ALL IS CALM
ALL IS BRIGHT ♪
♪ ROUND YON VIRGIN
MOTHER AND CHILD ♪
>>> AND COMING UP, A CNN
EXCLUSIVE.
WE'RE GOING TO HEAR FROM THE
FAMILY OF THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY PRINCIPAL WHO LOST
HER LIFE TRYING TO CONFRONT A
KILLER.
[ Female Announcer ] BORN FROM
THE NATURALLY SWEET MONK FRUIT,
SOMETHING THIS DELICIOUS
COULD ONLY COME FROM NATURE.
NOW FROM THE MAKER
OF SPLENDA SWEETENERS,
DISCOVER NECTRESSE.
THE ONLY 100% NATURAL,
NO-CALORIE SWEETENER
MADE FROM THE GOODNESS
OF FRUIT.
THE RICH, SWEET TASTE OF SUGAR.
NOTHING ARTIFICIAL.
♪
IT'S ALL THAT SWEET
EVER NEEDS TO BE.
NEW NECTRESSE.
SWEETNESS NATURALLY.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO THIS SPECIAL
EDITION OF "EARLY START" THIS
MORNING FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
SHE WAS THE PRINCIPAL OF SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
NOW, DAWN HOCHSPRUNG IS BEING
REMEMBERED AS A HERO, WHO TRIED
TO SUBDUE THE GUNMAN BEFORE SHE
WAS KILLED.
>> WE SAT DOWN WITH A
CONVERSATION WITH HER FAMILY.
>> Reporter: PRINCIPAL DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG WAS QUITE A BIT
YOUNGER THAN HER HUSBAND,
GEORGE.
BUT WHEN THEY GOT MARRIED, FOR
THE SECOND TIME, GEORGE WAS
MARRYING HIS BOSS.
>> SHE WAS AN ASSISTANT
PRINCIPAL AT OUR SCHOOL.
AND I WAS A SEVENTH GRADE MATH
TEACHER AT THAT TIME.
AND I JUST FELL IN LOVE WITH
HER.
>> Reporter: GEORGE MADE THE BIG
DECISION.
THE TIME HAD COME TO PROPOSE.
>> SHE TURNED ME DOWN FIVE
TIMES.
>> Reporter: YOU ASKED HER TO
MARRY HER.
AND SHE TURNED YOU DOWN?
>> FIVE TIMES.
>> Reporter: WHAT HAPPENED THE
SIXTH TIME?
>> THE SIXTH TIME, I WAITED
UNTIL IT WASN'T SO ROUGH
SAILING.
>> Reporter: GEORGE HAD BEEN
POPPING THE QUESTION ON A
SAILBOAT THEY BOUGHT TOGETHER.
>> WE GOT MARRIED ON A SLOOP.
>> Reporter: BETH, AMY AND ANN
ARE HIS DAUGHTERS FROM HIS FIRST
MARRIAGE.
THE OTHER DAUGHTER, TINA, WAS
OUT WHILE WE WERE AT THE HOUSE.
THEY ARE A CLOSE BUT BLENDED
FAMILY.
>> THE DREAM WAS, CHRONOLOGICAL
DREAM.
IT WAS GOING TO BE DAWN'S HOUSE.
I WAS GOING TO DIE.
I'M MUCH OLDER THAN DAWN.
IT WAS GOING TO BE DAWN'S HOUSE.
ALL OF THE CHILDREN AND THE
GRANDCHILDREN COULD USE THE
HOUSE ON THE LAKE.
WE BUILT ROOMS DOWNSTAIRS FOR
KIDS.
IT WAS GOING TO BE DAWN'S HOUSE
ULTIMATELY, WITH ALL OF THE
CHILDREN.
ALL THE CHILDREN.
AND NOW, IT'S ME.
I CAN'T -- I DON'T THINK I CAN
DO THAT.
>> Reporter: BUT I WANT TO
REITERATE TO YOU, GEORGE.
YOU HAVE THESE BEAUTIFUL
DAUGHTERS AND SONS-IN-LAW AND
GRANDCHILDREN.
AND EVERYONE WILL BE HERE TO
TAKE CARE OF YOU.
IS THAT RIGHT, LADIES?
>> MY JOB IS TO TAKE CARE OF
OTHER PEOPLE.
>> Reporter: IT'S ALL RIGHT IF
SOMEONE TAKES CARE OF YOU FOR A
WHILE.
>> STOP BEING SO STUBBORN.
>> Reporter: GEORGE STILL TAUGHT
AT THE MIDDLE SCHOOL WHERE THEY
MET.
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE DAY FRIDAY,
THIS IS HOW GEORGE FOUND OUT
WHAT HAPPENED.
>> ONE OF THE KIDS CAME UP WITH
A COMPUTER.
AND SAID, SOMETHING'S HAPPENING
AT SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
AND YOUR WIFE'S BEEN KILLED.
>> Reporter: GEORGE RACED OUT OF
SCHOOL.
AND INTO A NIGHTMARE.
LIKE ALL OF THE FAMILIES OF
VICTIMS, THEY WANT TO KNOW MORE.
AND ON THIS DAY, THEY HAVE
LEARNED MORE.
TWO TEACHERS WHO SURVIVED TOLD
GEORGE THEY WERE HAVING A
MEETING WITH DAWN WHEN THE SHOTS
STARTED RINGING OUT.
>> DAWN PUT HERSELF IN JEOPARDY.
AND I HAVE BEEN ANGRY ABOUT
THAT.
ANGRY.
UNTIL JUST NOW, WHEN I MET TWO
WOMEN THAT SHE TOLD TO GO UNDER
SHELTER WHILE SHE ACTUALLY
CONFRONTED THE GUNMAN.
SHE COULD HAVE AVOIDED THAT.
AND SHE DIDN'T.
I KNEW SHE WOULDN'T.
SO, I'M NOT ANGRY ANYMORE.
I'M NOT ANGRY.
I'M NOT ANGRY AT ANYONE.
I'M JUST VERY SAD.
THEY WERE AT THE MEETING.
THERE WERE GUNSHOTS.
SOMEBODY SHOT THE WINDOW.
SOMEBODY CAME IN, INTO THE --
NOT INTO THE OFFICE, BUT INTO
THE BUILDING, THE FOYER OF THE
BUILDING.
AND DAWN TOLD US TO GO HIDE.
AND SHE AND AT LEAST ONE OTHER
TEACHER WENT OUT AND ACTUALLY
TRIED TO SUBDUE THE KILLER.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE THAT COMES
FROM.
DAWN WAS 5'2".
>> Reporter: EVERYONE HERE IS SO
PROUD.
NO ONE MORE SO THAN ERICA, WHO
SAID HER MOM WAS THERE FOR HER
DAUGHTERS.
>> EVERY GAME, SHE WAS THERE.
EVERY CHEERLEADING STUFF, SHE
WAS THERE.
EVERY DANCE COMPETITION.
SHE WAS DOING HOMEWORK ON THE
BLEACHERS.
BUT SHE WAS THERE.
AND SHE WAS MY ROCK.
MY ROCK.
>> Reporter: AND NOW, SHE IS A
HERO, TOO.
FINAL THING I WANT TO ASK YOU
IS, WHAT WOULD YOU SAY TO YOUR
MOM RIGHT NOW?
>> COME BACK.
JUST COME BACK.
>> YES, YES, YES.
>> THAT WAS GARY TUCHMAN
REPORTING.
IT'S REALLY DIFFICULT, I WOULD
IMAGINE, FOR THE FAMILIES.
BUT FOR ALL OF US TO HEAR THEIR
STORIES AND KNOW HOW THEY WERE
IN LIFE, IS REALLY, I THINK,
SPECTACULAR.
>> IT IS.
>> IT HELPS WITH CLOSURE AND
HOPE.
>> IT'S TOUGH TO HEAR THIS MAN
SAY THAT HE WAS SUPPOSED TO DIE
FIRST.
THAT THEY BOUGHT THE HOUSE.
AND SHE WAS SUPPOSED TO LIVE IN
IT.
AND SHE DOESN'T WAHE DOESN'T WA
CARE OF.
IT MAKES IT REALLY, REAL.
>> WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
Woman ] R
MIXES WITH POLLEN AND DUST.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
YOU WON'T JUST
FIND US ONLINE,
YOU'LL ALSO FIND US IN PERSON,
WITH DEDICATED SUPPORT TEAMS
AT OVER 500 BRANCHES
NATIONWIDE.
SO WHEN YOU CALL OR VISIT,
YOU CAN ASK FOR A NAME
YOU KNOW.
BECAUSE PERSONAL SERVICE
STARTS WITH A REAL PERSON.
[ Rodger ]
AT SCOTTRADE,
SEVEN DOLLAR TRADES
ARE JUST THE START.
OUR SUPPORT TEAMS
ARE NEARBY,
READY TO HELP.
IT'S NO WONDER SO MANY INVESTORS
ARE SAYING...
[ All ]
I'M WITH SCOTTRADE.
CAMPBELL'S HAS 24 NEW SOUPS
THAT WILL MAKE IT DROP OVER,
AND OVER AGAIN.
♪
FROM JAMMIN' JERK CHICKEN,
TO CREAMY GOUDA BISQUE.
SEE WHAT'S NEW FROM CAMPBELL'S.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
A REGULAR GUY
WITH AN IRREGULAR HEARTBEAT.
THE USUAL, BOB?
NOT TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
BOB HAS AFIB:
ATRIAL FIBRILLATION NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
A CONDITION THAT PUTS HIM
AT GREATER RISK FOR A STROKE.
[ GPS ] TURN LEFT.
I DON'T THINK SO.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR YEARS, BOB TOOK WARFARIN,
AND MADE A MONTHLY TRIP TO THE
CLINIC TO GET HIS BLOOD TESTED.
BUT NOT ANYMORE.
BOB'S DOCTOR RECOMMENDED
A DIFFERENT OPTION:
ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
XARELTO® IS THE FIRST AND ONLY
ONCE-A-DAY PRESCRIPTION
BLOOD THINNER
FOR PATIENTS WITH AFIB
NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
THAT DOESN'T REQUIRE
ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING.
LIKE WARFARIN,
XARELTO® IS PROVEN EFFECTIVE
TO REDUCE THE RISK
OF AN AFIB-RELATED STROKE.
THERE IS LIMITED DATA
ON HOW THESE DRUGS COMPARE
WHEN WARFARIN IS WELL MANAGED.
NO ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING
MEANS BOB CAN SPEND HIS
EXTRA TIME HOWEVER HE LIKES.
NEW ZEALAND!
XARELTO®
IS JUST ONE PILL A DAY,
TAKEN WITH THE EVENING MEAL.
AND WITH
NO DIETARY RESTRICTIONS,
BOB CAN EAT THE HEALTHY FOODS
HE LIKES.
DO NOT STOP TAKING
XARELTO® RIVAROXABAN
WITHOUT TALKING TO THE DOCTOR
WHO PRESCRIBES IT FOR YOU.
STOPPING MAY INCREASE YOUR RISK
OF HAVING A STROKE.
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU DEVELOP ANY SIGNS
OR SYMPTOMS OF BLEEDING,
LIKE UNUSUAL BRUISING
OR TINGLING.
YOU MAY HAVE A HIGHER RISK
OF BLEEDING
IF YOU TAKE XARELTO®
WITH ASPIRIN PRODUCTS,
NSAIDS OR BLOOD THINNERS.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE TAKING XARELTO®
IF YOU CURRENTLY HAVE
ABNORMAL BLEEDING.
XARELTO® CAN CAUSE BLEEDING,
WHICH CAN BE SERIOUS,
AND RARELY MAY LEAD TO DEATH.
YOU ARE LIKELY TO BRUISE
MORE EASILY ON XARELTO®,
AND IT MAY TAKE LONGER
FOR BLEEDING TO STOP.
TELL YOUR DOCTORS
YOU ARE TAKING XARELTO®
BEFORE ANY PLANNED MEDICAL
OR DENTAL PROCEDURES.
BEFORE STARTING XARELTO®,
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ANY CONDITIONS,
SUCH AS KIDNEY, LIVER
OR BLEEDING PROBLEMS.
READY TO CHANGE YOUR ROUTINE?
ASK YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
FOR MORE INFORMATION
INCLUDING COST SUPPORT OPTIONS,
CALL 1-888-XARELTO
OR VISIT GOXARELTO.COM.
>>> WELCOME BACK.
WE ARE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
WHERE THIS MORNING A GRIEVING
COMMUNITY PREPARING FOR THE
FIRST OF MORE THAN TWO DOZEN
FUNERALS.
TODAY, THEY WILL BURY TWO
6-YEAR-OLD BOYS.
JACK PINTO, A BIG NEW YORK
GIANTS FANS.
AND NOAH POZNER, TWO THAT WERE
SLAIN FRIDAY AT THE SANDY HOOK
MEMORIAL SCHOOL.
>> POLICE ARE TRYING TO PIECE
TOGETHER EVERYTHING THAT WENT
ON.
WE'RE TRYING TO FIND OUT MORE
ABOUT THE SHOOTER THIS MORNING.
WHY HE MAY HAVE BEEN TARGETING
THE SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
AND HOW HE GOT IN THOSE DOORS TO
BEGIN THIS DEADLY RAMPAGE.
>>> AND FOR A LOOK AT SOME OF
THE OTHER STORIES MAKING NEWS
THIS MORNING, WE'RE GOING TO GO
TO CHRISTINE ROMANS.
>> KILLED IN THE LINE OF DUTY,
TWO KANSAS POLICE OFFICERS SHOT
WHILE RESPONDING TO REPORTS OF A
SUSPICIOUS CAR AT A GROCERY
STORE.
THEY DIED LAST NIGHT AT TOPEKA
HOSPITAL.
A THIRD OFFICER ON THE SCENE WAS
NOT HIT.
THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER,
22-YEAR-OLD DAVID TISCARENO IS
ON THE RUN.
HE IS CONSIDERED DANGEROUS.
>>> THE STATE DEPARTMENT IS
EXPECTED TO GET THE RESULTS ON
THE TERROR ATTACK ON THE
CONSULATE IN BENGHAZI.
HEARINGS ON THE FLOOR OF THE
HOUSE AND THE SENATE START
THURSDAY.
>>> SENATOR JOHN KERRY IS
EXPECTED TO BE PRESIDENT OBAMA'S
NOMINEE FOR NEXT SECRETARY OF
STATE.
IN HIS CURRENT ROLE AS SENATE
FOREIGN RELATIONS COMMITTEE,
KERRY HAD TRAVELED THE WORLD TO
SMOOTH OVER STRAINED
RELATIONSHIP, IS INCLUDING TO
PAKISTAN AFTER THE DEATH OF
OSAMA BIN LADEN.
>>> ALL EYES REMAIN ON
WASHINGTON TO SEE IF LAWMAKERS
CAN STRIKE A DEAL TO AVOID TAX
INCREASES AND SPENDING CUTS OVER
THE NEXT DECADE.
>>> THE NIKKEI 225 INDEX IN
JAPAN IS TRADING HIGHER TODAY.
THE WIN WILL MOST LIKELY RESULT
IN A LOOSENING OF JAPAN'S
MONETARY POLICY.
>>> DESPITE UPBEAT ON THE
ECONOMIC DATA, MARKETS ENDED
LOWER LAST WEEK.
IT'S ALL ABOUT THE FISCAL CLIFF,
RIGHT?
COULD WASHINGTON BE MAKING
STRIDES?
YESTERDAY, A SOURCE FAMILIAR
WITH THE TALKS TOLD CNN THAT
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER IS
WILLING TO EXTEND THE DEBT LIMIT
FOR A YEAR.
THE CEILING STANDS AT $16.4
TRILLION.
RAISING IT FURTHER, REQUIRES AN
ACTED OF CONGRESS, SOMETHING THE
REPUBLICANS HAVE OPPOSED SINCE
GAINING THE HOUSE IN 2010.
THAT NEWS CAME A DAY AFTER A
SOURCE SAID BOEHNER HAD
SUGGESTED HIGHER TAXES ON
AMERICANS WITH ANNUAL INCOMES
OVER $1 MILLION.
HIGHER THAN WHAT THE PRESIDENT
WANTS.
PRESIDENT WANTS HIGHER TAXES ON
EVERYBODY OVER $250,000.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>>> AND COMING UP, MUCH MORE
LIVE FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
WHERE THE NATION LOOKED TO
PRESIDENT OBAMA FOR COMFORT LAST
NIGHT.
AND WHERE DETECTIVES CONTINUE TO
LOOK FOR ANSWERS TODAY.
[ Woman ] DEAR CAT, YOUR HAIR
MIXES WITH POLLEN AND DUST.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
SOMETHING THIS DELICIOUS
COULD ONLY COME FROM NATURE.
NEW NECTRESSE.
THE 100% NATURAL
NO-CALORIE SWEETENER
MADE FROM THE GOODNESS
OF FRUIT.
NEW NECTRESSE.
SWEETNESS NATURALLY.
>>> AND YOU MUST KNOW THAT
WHATEVER MEASURE OF COMFORT WE
CAN PROVIDE, WE WILL PROVIDE IT.
WHATEVER PORTION OF SADNESS THAT
WE CAN SHARE WITH YOU TO EASE
THIS HEAVY LOAD, WE WILL GLADLY
BEAR IT.
NEWTOWN, YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
>> NOWTOWN, YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA OFFERING COMFORT
TO THIS GRIEVING COMMUNITY, AS
NEWTOWN PREPARES TO BEGIN
BURYING THE VICTIMS OF THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SHOOTING.
WELCOME BACK TO THIS SPECIAL
EDITION OF "EARLY START."
>> IT IS A RAW AND GRAY MORNING
HERE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THIS CLOSE KNIT COMMUNITY IS
STILL REELING, STILL NUMB, THREE
DAYS AFTER THE SENSELESS
SLAUGHTER AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL ON FRIDAY.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA PAID A VISIT
LAST NIGHT.
FIRST, HE COMFORTED FAMILY
MEMBERS IN PRIVATE.
THEN, PUBLICLY ASSURING THEM,
YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
HE PROMISED TO USE ALL THE
POWERS HE HAS AS PRESIDENT TO
STOP THESE KINDS OF TRAGEDIES.
>> TODAY, NEWTOWN BEGINS BURYING
ITS DEAD, STARTING WITH TWO
6-YEAR-OLD BOYS.
JACK PINTO, WHO LOVED HIS
NEW YORK GIANTS.
AND NOAH POZNER.
HE IS THE YOUNGEST VICTIM WHO
WAS SHOT 11 TIMES.
POLICE TRYING TO PIECE TOGETHER
THE PUZZLE HERE.
HOW THE SHOOTER GOT INTO THE
SCHOOL.
AND WHY SANDY HOOK MAY HAVE BEEN
HIS TARGET.
AND THE BROKENHEARTED FAMILY OF
PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG
SPEAKING EXCLUSIVELY TO CNN,
WITH THE FINAL MOMENTS AND HER
LEGACY.
>> FIRST, WE GO TO SANDRA
OUTSIDE A CHURCH IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THIS CLOSE-KNIT COMMUNITY IS
COMING TOGETHER TO SAY GOOD-BYE.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
VERY HEAVY HEARTS, INDEED, IN
THIS ENTIRE COMMUNITY.
AND LAST NIGHT, PRESIDENT OBAMA
CAME HERE TO ADDRESS THE
RESIDENTS IN NEWTOWN, TO TALK
ABOUT HOW HE IS VOWING TO MAKE
SURE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS DON'T
HAPPEN AGAIN.
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS, I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE
HOLDS, TO ENGAGE LAW
ENFORCEMENT, MENTAL HEALTH
PROFESSIONALS AND EDUCATORS, IN
AN EFFORT AIMED TO PREVENTING
MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS.
>> Reporter: THE PRESIDENT ALSO
MET WITH VICTIMS' FAMILY MEMBERS
AT A VIGIL TO REMEMBER THE LIVES
LOST IN FRIDAY'S TRAGEDY.
HE EXPRESSED CONDOLENCES FROM AN
ENTIRE NATION.
>> I COME TO OFFER THE LOVE AND
PRAYERS OF THE NATION.
I AM VERY MINDFUL THAT MERE
WORDS CANNOT MATCH THE DEPTHS OF
YOUR SORROW.
NOR CAN THEY HEAL YOUR WOUNDED
HEARTS.
I CAN ONLY HOPE IT HELPS FOR YOU
TO KNOW THAT YOU'RE NOT ALONE IN
YOUR GRIEF.
>> Reporter: DEFINITELY NOT
ALONE.
TODAY, THE FIRST OF MANY
FUNERALS.
BEING LAID TO REST THIS
AFTERNOON, 6-YEAR-OLD NOAH
POZNER.
HE HAS A TWIN SISTER, WHO FAMILY
MEMBERS SAY STILL DOES NOT KNOW
THE EXACT WAY HER BROTHER DIED.
ALSO BEING BURIED TODAY,
6-YEAR-OLD JACK PINTO.
HE WAS A HUGE SPORTS FAN.
AND IDOLIZED GIANTS RECEIVER
VICTOR CRUZ.
CRUZ PAID TRIBUTE TO PINTO,
WRITING ON HIS CHEATS, REST IN
PEACE, JACK PINTO.
>> SO MANY AND WILL CONTINUE TO
BE SO MANY MORE.
HARD TO SEE.
THERE ARE A LOT OF KIDS, SANDRA,
IN THIS COMMUNITY, WHO WANT TO
KNOW WHAT'S NEXT FOR THEM.
WHEN WILL THEY BE RETURNING TO
SCHOOL?
AND WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT WHAT'S
GOING TO HAPPEN WITH THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL?
>> Reporter: IT'S A DELICATE
BALANCE.
ADMINISTRATORS WANT TO RETURN TO
A SENSE OF NORMALCY FOR A LOT OF
THESE KIDS.
AT THE SAME TIME, THIS IS SUCH A
TRAGIC EVENT.
SCHOOLS IN THIS COMMUNITY WILL
REMAIN CLOSED TODAY, SO THE
STAFF CAN TALK TO EXPERTS TO
FIGURE OUT HOW TO DEAL WITH THIS
TRAGEDY.
ALL CLASSES WILL RESUME
TOMORROW, EXCEPT FOR SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
THEY ARE WORKING OUT WITH A
NEIGHBORING TOWN HOW TO
ACCOMMODATE ALL OF THOSE
COMMUNITIES.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>>> CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
HAVE NOT YET REVEALED A POSSIBLE
MOTIVE FOR THE SHOOTINGS.
BUT AS THEIR INVESTIGATION
CONTINUES, WE'RE STARTING TO
LEARN A BIT MORE.
THE GUNMAN HAS BEEN POSITIVELY
IDENTIFIED.
AND WE NOW KNOW HE SHOT HIS WAY
INTO THE SCHOOL AND WAS NOT
BUZZED IN.
ALISON KOSIK IS IN NEWTOWN.
GOOD MORNING, ALISON.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING.
LINKING ON WHAT YOU SAID.
HOW HE GOT INTO THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
SOURCES ARE TELLING US, THAT HE
BLASTED HIS WAY IN.
HE SHOT HIS WAY, CREATING AN
ENTRANCE TO GET INSIDE THE
SCHOOL.
DESPITE, YES, THE DOORS WERE
LOCKED AS OF 9:30.
YOU HAD TO BE BUZZED IN TO GET
INTO THE SCHOOL.
AND AUTHORITIES ARE SAYING, ONCE
INSIDE THE SCHOOL, HE FOCUSED
HIS SHOOTING ON TWO CLASSROOMS
AND IN THE HALLWAY.
POLICE SAY THEY FOUND THREE
WEAPONS ON HIM INSIDE THE
SCHOOL, THAT HE FIRED DOZENS OF
BULL
BULLETS, A SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE
ON HIS VICTIMS AND A HANDGUN TO
KILL HIMSELF.
>> THE WEAPON THAT WAS UTILIZED
MOST OF THE TIME DURING THIS
CRIME, WAS A BUSHMASTER AR-15
ASSAULT WEAPON.
IT HAD ADDITION AAL MAGAZINES.
AND HE HAD A GLOCK AND A 6
MILLIMETER.
ALL WEAPONS HAD ADDITIONAL
MAGAZINES AND ADDITIONAL
AMMUNITION.
THE FOURTH WEAPON WE RECOVERED
WAS A SHOTGUN, RECOVERED FROM
THE SUSPECT'S VEHICLE, THAT WAS
PARKED OUTSIDE OF A SCHOOL.
>> Reporter: HE TALKS ABOUT
AMMUNITION THAT HE STILL HAD
WITH HIM, HE'S TALKING ABOUT HE
HAD HUNDREDS OF BULLETS WITH HIM
THAT WERE NOT USED.
AS FOR THE MOTIVE, INVESTIGATORS
SAY THEY HAVE A LOT OF WORK
AHEAD OF THEM, THEY HAVE AN
IMMENSE AMOUNT OF WITNESSES TO
TALK WITH INCLUDING CHILDREN.
>> I WAS WATCHING THE PRESS
CONFERENCE YESTERDAY.
THEY SAID THEY'RE BEING VERY
THOROUGH AND EXHAUSTIVE IN THEIR
INVESTIGATION HERE.
DO WE KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT THE
GUNMAN'S ACTIVETICTIVITIES LEAD
TO THE SHOOTING?
>> Reporter: THAT'S WHAT THEY
WANT TO KNOW.
THE DAYS AND WEEKS AND MONTHS
LEADING UP TO THE SHOOTING.
THEY ALREADY HAVE PROOF IN A THE
GUNMAN WAS AT LEAST ONE GUN
RANGE.
THEY'RE NOT TELLING US WITH WHEN
OR WHERE.
THEY SAY HIS MOTHER WAS ALSO AT
MULTIPLE GUN RANGES.
THEY'RE NOT GIVING A TIMELINE
FOR THAT, EITHER.
FEDERAL AGENTS CONTINUE CHASING
LEADS, THOUGH.
THEY ARE, YOU KNOW, LOOKING AT
AS MANY AS 30 GUN RANGES, 400
GUN DEALERS IN THE SURROUNDING
AREA, TRYING TO UNDERSTAND WHAT
THE ACTIVITIES WERE OF THIS
GUNMAN LEADING UP TO THIS
MASSACRE.
>> ALISON KOSIK, REPORTING LIVE
FOR US.
JOHN, YESTERDAY, WHEN I WAS
WATCHING, HE SAID THEY ARE GOING
TO TRACE THAT GUN.
THEY'LL KNOW WHERE IT WAS SOLD,
HOW MUCH IT TRAVELED.
>> THEY HAVE A LOT MORE TO
FIGURE OUT.
>>> IT'S BEEN TRUE THAT GUN
CONTROL HAS NOT BEEN ON THE
NATIONAL RADAR FOR MANY YEARS
NOW.
NOW, THE DEBATE IS RAGING AGAIN.
FOR STRICTER GUN LAWS.
THERE'S SO MANY WEAPONS IN THIS
COUNTRY.
AND PEOPLE ARE SAYING ENOUGH IS
ENOUGH.
OF COURSE, OPPONENTS OF GUN
CONTROL SAY, IF PEOPLE IN THE
SCHOOL HAD HAD GUNS, THEY WOULD
HAVE BEEN ABLE TO DEFEND
THEMSELVES.
DAVID AXELROD, THE MAN WHO RAN
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S RE-ELECTION
CAMPAIGN --
>> MORE THAN THREE PEOPLE IN
RECENT HISTORY, HAS BEEN IN A
PLACE WHERE GUNS WERE
PROHIBITED.
>> AND IT HAPPENS AGAIN AND
AGAIN.
THERE WAS ANOTHER SHOOTING
YESTERDAY.
THREE PEOPLE KILLED, I THINK, IN
A HOSPITAL.
WE KILL PEOPLE IN SCHOOLS.
WE KILL THEM IN HOSPITALS.
WE KILL THEM IN RELIGIOUS
ORGANIZATIONS.
WE KILL THEM WHEN THEY ARE
YOUNG.
WE KILL THEM WHEN THEY ARE OLD.
AND WE JUST HAVE TO STOP THIS.
>> DAVID AXELROD, THE MAN WHO
HELPED RUN PRESIDENT OBAMA'S
RE-ELECTION CAMPAIGN TWEETED
THIS YESTERDAY.
CHECK THIS OUT.
HE SAID, IN NFL POSTGAME, AN AD
FOR SHOOT 'EM UP VIDEO GAMES.
SHOULDN'T WE QUIT MARKETING
MURDER AS A GAME?
THAT RAISED EYEBROWS AFTER THE
FOOTBALL GAME FROM DAVID
AXELROD.
>> I'M HOPEFUL, AS I'M SURE YOU
ARE, IT'S GOING TO BE THOUGHTFUL
DIALOGUE.
AND AT THE END OF THE DAY, THERE
WILL BE CHANGE.
IT IS SAD TO THINK THIS WOULD
HAVE SPURNED IT.
>> THERE'S BEEN AN ENORMOUS
AMOUNT OF TALK.
THE DISCUSSION IS RAGING ALL
WEEKEND.
IT WILL CONTINUE THIS WEEK.
BUT THE QUESTION IS, WILL THERE
OR WHEN WILL THERE BE ACTION?
>>> THE NEWTOWN TRAGEDY WAS FELT
IN THE NFL ON SUNDAY.
VICTOR CRUZ HONORED ONE OF THE
VICTIMS.
WATCHING JACK PRISINTO, ON HIS
CLEATS.
AND SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY ON HIS
HELMET.
VICTOR CRUZ SPOKE TO THE FATHER
AFTER LEARNING HIS SON WAS A BIG
FAN.
AND HE SPENT TIME TALKING TO THE
PARENTS AND TO THE LITTLE
BROTHER, AS WELL.
HE SAID IT WAS HIS WAY TO BE
ABLE TO GIVE BACK A LITTLE BIT
BECAUSE HE WAS DEVASTATED BY
THIS.
AND I THINK ACROSS THE COUNTRY,
THAT'S WHAT WE SEE.
EVERYBODY IS TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT, WHAT CAN I DO?
THEY FEEL HELPLESS IN A TRAGEDY
LIKE THIS.
>> THE NEW ENGLAND PATRIOTS WORE
AN INSIGNIA ON THEIR HELMETS.
AND EVERYONE COMING TOGETHER AS
A TOWN, A STATE AND A COUNTRY.
>> FOR INFORMATION ABOUT HOW YOU
CAN HELP THOSE WHO ARE AFFECTED,
GO TO CNN.COM/IMPACT.
>>> ON ONE OF AMERICA'S DARKEST
DAYS, THE SELFLESS FINAL ACT OF
A TEACHER WILL BE REMEMBERED.
WE'LL HAVE HER STORY, COMING UP.
[ Woman ] DEAR CAT, YOUR HAIR
MIXES WITH POLLEN AND DUST.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
[ engine revs ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THE MERCEDES-BENZ WINTER EVENT
IS BACK,
WITH THE PERFECT VEHICLE
THAT'S JUST RIGHT FOR YOU,
NO MATTER WHICH LIST YOU'RE ON.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
ML350 FOR $599 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAND.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
WE DON'T LET FREQUENT HEARTBURN
COME BETWEEN US
AND WHAT WE LOVE.
SO IF YOU'RE ONE OF THEM PEOPLE
WHO GETS HEARTBURN
AND THEN TREATS DAY AFTER DAY...
BLOCK THE ACID WITH PRILOSEC OTC
AND DON'T GET HEARTBURN
IN THE FIRST PLACE!
[ Male Announcer ]
ONE PILL EACH MORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBURN.
>>> ADMINISTRATORS AND TEACHERS
AT SANDY HOOK ARE BEING HAILED
FOR THEIR HEROISM, FOR SAVING
THE LIVES OF THE CHILDREN BEFORE
WORRYING ABOUT THEMSELVES.
ONE OF THOSE TEACHERS WAS
27-YEAR-OLD VICTORIA SOTO.
SHE LED HER FIRST GRADERS AWAY
FROM THE CLASSROOM DOOR, ONLY TO
BE SHOT AND KILLED BY THE
GUNMAN.
VICKI SOTO'S FAMILY SAYS THE
FIRST GRADE TEACHER DIED DOING
WHAT SHE LOVED.
AND SPENT HER FINAL MOMENTS
PROTECTING THE CHILDREN THAT
MEANT THE WORLD TO HER.
>> THERE ARE KIDS NOW THAT WILL
BE ABLE TO SAY THAT THEY'RE HERE
TODAY BECAUSE SHE SACRIFICED HER
LIFE SO THEY COULD LIVE ANOTHER
DAY.
>> Reporter: SOTO IS BEING
CALLED A HERO FOR SHIELDING HER
YOUNG STUDENTS FROM HARM.
SHE HID HER FIRST GRADERS IN A
CLOSET.
BUT HER MOTHER, DONNA SOTO, IS
NOT SURPRISED BY HER 27-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHTER'S ACTIONS.
>> SHE WAS TRULY SELFLESS.
SHE WOULD NOT HESITATE TO SAVE
ANYONE ELSE BEFORE HERSELF.
AND ESPECIALLY CHILDREN.
SHE LOVED THEM MORE THAN LIFE.
AND SHE WOULD DEFINITELY PUT
HERSELF IN FRONT OF THEM ANY
DAY.
ANY DAY AND FOR ANY REASON.
IT DOESN'T SURPRISE ANYBODY THAT
KNOWS VICKI THAT SHE DID THIS.
>> Reporter: DONNA SOTO SAYS
THAT VICKI KNEW SINCE THE AGE OF
3, SHE WANTED TO BE A TEACHER.
>> THAT'S ALL SHE WANTED TO DO.
SHE JUST LOVED HER KIDS.
HE TALKED ABOUT THEM ALL THE
TIME WITH SUCH FONDNESS AND
CARING.
AND SHE JUST ADORED THEM.
>> Reporter: THIS WEEKEND,
FAMILY FOUND COMFORT AT VIGILS
FOR VICKI.
ONE IN HER HOMETOWN OF
STRATFORD.
>> IT'S GREAT TO KNOW THAT
EVERYONE IN STRATFORD HAS BEEN
TOUCHED SOMEHOW.
AND THAT CAME HERE TO CELEBRATE
HER LIFE.
>> Reporter: ALSO CELEBRATING
HER LIFE, PRESIDENT OBAMA, WHO
SPENT TIME WITH THE FAMILY,
PRIOR TO A VIGIL FOR VICTIMS IN
NEWTOWN.
>> HE WAS VERY CARING AND VERY
SUPPORTIVE.
AND TOLD US HE KNEW ALL ABOUT
VICKI AND WHAT SHE DID AND WHAT
A HERO SHE WAS.
AND HE WAS JUST VERY, VERY KIND
TO US.
AND GAVE US THE TIME WE NEEDED
WITH HIM.
AND IT WAS -- IT WAS VERY
COMFORTING.
>> VICTORIA WAS ONE OF SIX
ADULTS, ALL WOMEN, KILLED INSIDE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
20 CHILDREN AND 6 ADULTS IN ALL,
WERE GUNNED DOWN AT THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE WANT TO HONOR ALL OF THE
VICTIMS.
LIKE 6-YEAR-OLD CHARLOTTE BACON.
CHARLOTTE BEGGED HER MOM TO LET
HER WEAR A NEW PINK DRESS AND
BOOTS TO SCHOOL, A HOLIDAY
OUTFIT.
7-YEAR-OLD DANIEL BARDEN.
A BUDDING ATHLETE.
HE SWAM.
HE PLAYED SOCCER.
HIS FAMILY CALLED HIM FEARLESS.
OLIVIA ENGLE, WAS JUST 6 YEARS
OLD.
SHE DID BALLET AND PLAYED
SOCCER.
AND HER FAMILY SAID SHE LOVED
SCHOOL.
>> JOSEPH GAY, JUST TURNED 7
LAST TUESDAY.
SHE LOVED THE COLOR PURPLE.
JOSEPHINE GAY, I SHOULD SAY.
AND ANA MARQUEZ-GREENE JUST 6
YEARS OLD.
ANA GREW UP WITH MUSIC IN HER
EARS.
HER FATHER WRITES MUSIC.
AND THERE WAS A 2009 SONG HE
WROTE ABOUT HER, "ANA GRACE."
I WAS THINKING, YOU DID THE
LOVELY PIECE ABOUT THE TEACHER.
VICTORIA SOTO.
JUST 27 YEARS OLD.
HER LIFE WAS TEACHING.
HER LIFE WAS EDUCATION.
LIKE THE SIX WOMEN KILLED AT
THAT SCHOOL, THEIR LIVES WERE
EDUCATION.
AND THEY GAVE THEIR LIVES FOR
IT.
>> WHEN YOU HEAR THEIR STORIES
OF HEROISM, AS PARENTS, YOU HOPE
THAT'S WHAT'S IN THE CLASSROOM.
YOU NEVER THINK OF TEACHERS
HAVING TO GIVE THEIR LIVES FOR
THEIR STUDENTS.
IT'S HEARTBREAKING.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA, OF COURSE,
LAST NIGHT WAS PLAYING THE ROLE
OF COMFORTER IN CHIEF.
TELLING THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN,
THEY ARE NOT ALONE.
WE'LL HAVE MORE FROM THE
EMOTIONAL AND MOVING VIGIL,
GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] CAMPBELL'S
GREEN BEAN CASSEROLE.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO
SOMETHING THIS DELICIOUS
COULD ONLY COME FROM NATURE.
NEW NECTRESSE.
THE 100% NATURAL
NO-CALORIE SWEETENER
MADE FROM THE GOODNESS
OF FRUIT.
NEW NECTRESSE.
SWEETNESS NATURALLY.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYONE, TO
OUR SPECIAL COVERAGE OF THE
SHOOTING AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE'LL HAVE MORE OF OUR COVERAGE.
BUT FIRST, HERE'S CHRISTINE
ROMANS IN NEW YORK.
>> ONLY 15 DAYS TO GO BEFORE THE
COUNTRY GOES OVER THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER
MAKING THE LATEST MOVE IN THE
NEGOTIATIONS.
HE HAS AGREED TO ALLOW TAX RATES
TO RISE ON HOUSEHOLD INCOMES OF
MORE THAN $1 MILLION A YEAR.
AND BOEHNER HAS OFFERED TO
EXTEND THE DEBT LIMIT OF ONE
YEAR AS PART OF A PROPOSED DEAL.
>>> SECRETARY OF STATE CLINTON
WILL WORK FROM HOME AS SHE
RECOVERS FROM A CONCUSSION.
SHE FAINTED DUE TO DEHYDRATION.
MAY HAVE BEEN DUE TO A STOMACH
FLU SHE BATTLED LAST WEEK.
>>> BLIZZARD CONDITIONS DEADLY
IN WASHINGTON STATE.
A TOW TRUCK DRIVER WAS STRUCK
AND KILLED ON INTERSTATE 90
WHILE TRYING TO TOW A CAR IN
NEAR WHITEOUT CONDITIONS.
IT'S THE WORST STORM TO HIT THAT
STATE IN MORE THAN FIVE YEARS.
>>> LET'S GO TO ROB MARCIANO.
GOOD MORNING, ROB.
>> THIS IS A DOOZY.
THE SNOWS HAVE BEEN PILING UP.
COLUMBIA RIVER BAR TRAFFIC, TO
GET IN TO USE THE RIVER TO
DELIVER THE GOODS HAS BEEN
PRETTY MUCH SHUT DOWN.
MORE RAIN AND SNOW ON THE WAY
HERE.
THEY'RE MEASURING IN FEET.
NOT ONLY ACROSS OREGON BUT
NORTHERN CALIFORNIA, AS WELL.
THE WINDS, INCREDIBLE.
ESPECIALLY AT THE HIGH
ELEVATIONS.
MARY'S PEAK, OREGON, 101.
BUT IN THE LOW LANDS.
AND LINCOLN CITY, AT SEA LEVEL,
81-MILE-PER-HOUR WIND GUSTS.
THE WINDS ARE GOING TO PUSH
INLAND TODAY.
SO, A LARGER SWATH OF REAL
ESTATE WILL BE ENDURING THESE,
AT TIMES, DAMAGING WINDS.
AND THE SNOW WILL PUSH INLAND.
THAT'S GOOD NEWS FOR THE AREAS
OF SALT LAKE CITY AND AROUND THE
COLORADO ROCKIES, WHERE THEY
COULD USE THE SNOW.
BUT THE SNOW WILL CREATE
AVALANCHE CONDITIONS ACROSS THE
CASCADES, WHERE THEY'VE SEEN
SEVERAL FEET OF SNOW.
NICE ACROSS THE MIDSECTION.
BUT THIS STORM, IF YOU LIVE IN
THE EAST COAST, YOU'RE DEALING
WITH IT RIGHT NOW, ESPECIALLY IN
THE NORTHEAST.
YOU GO NORTH OF NEWTOWN, AND
BRAD FORD, AND SOUTHERN
MASSACHUSETTS, FREEZING RAIN IN
SOME SPOTS.
OTHER PARTS OF NORTHERN
NEW ENGLAND, IN THE FORM OF
SNOW.
NEW YORK CITY THROUGH SOUTHERN
CONNECTICUT, COLD, DAMP, AND AT
TIMES, MISERABLE RAINFALL.
AND THE THUNDERSTORMS WILL ROLL
ACROSS PARTS OF THE SOUTH TODAY,
AS THEY HAD V LAST NIGHT.
44 DEGREES IN CHICAGO.
A CHILLY, RAW 46 DEGREES IN
NEW YORK CITY.
AND, JOHN, UP IN CONNECTICUT, A
FEW DEGREES COOLER IN THAT, AS
YOU'RE ENDURING RIGHT NOW.
BACK UP TO YOU.
>> THANKS, ROB.
AS YOU MENTIONED, IT IS A GRAY,
RAINY DAY HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
FITTING.
FUNERALS WILL BE HELD TODAY FOR
TWO OF THE CHILDREN KILLED IN
THE SANDY HOOK SCHOOL SHOOTING.
LAST NIGHT, PRESIDENT OBAMA
ATTENDED AN INTERFAITH MEMORIAL
SERVICE, IN HIS ROLE AS
COMFORTER IN CHIEF, AS THE
COMMUNITY TRIES TO MOVE ON IN
TRAGEDY.
>> WE ASK GOD TO GRANT THOSE
LOST A SPECIAL PLACE IN
PARADISE.
AND WE ASK THE FAMILIES TO BE
ABLE TO ENDURE THE UNDURABLE.
IT IS IN THESE TIMES OF LOSS
THAT WE SEEK THE COMFORT OF OUR
CREATOR.
AND THAT FAITH REVEALS MOTHERS,
FATHERS, BROTHERS AND SISTERS,
SONS AND DAUGHTERS.
>> WE WILL GO ON.
WE WILL FIND STRENGTH.
FAITH IS A GIFT, AS IS OUR
ABILITY TO SUPPORT ONE ANOTHER
IN OUR GREATER COMMUNITY.
TO ALL OF YOU, I EXTEND MY MOST
PROFOUND CONDOLENCES ON BEHALF
OF ALL OF YOUR FELLOW CITIZENS
FOR WHAT YOU HAVE SEEN, WHAT YOU
HAVE WITNESSED AND WHAT YOU HAVE
PERSONALLY EXPERIENCED.
>> AS A COMMUNITY, YOU'VE
INSPIRED US, NEWTOWN.
IN THE FACE OF INDESCRIBABLE
VIOLENCE, IN THE FACE OF
UNCONSCIONABLE EVIL, YOU'VE
LOOKED OUT FOR EACH OTHER,
YOU'VE CARED FOR ONE ANOTHER.
AND YOU'VE LOVED ONE ANOTHER.
THIS IS HOW NEWTOWN WILL BE
REMEMBERED.
AND WITH TIME AND GOD'S GRACE,
THAT LOVE WILL SEE YOU THROUGH.
>> JUST SOME OF THE MOVING WORDS
WE SAW LAST NIGHT AT THIS VIGIL.
IN A SHORT WHILE, WE'LL TALK TO
JASON GRAYS.
ONE OF THE MEN YOU SAW THERE.
>>> AND COMING UP NOW,
REMEMBERING THE VICTIMS OF THE
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL SHOOTING.
AND WE'LL HAVE THE LATEST, OF
COURSE, ON THE POLICE
INVESTIGATION.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
MIXES WITH .
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
HOW THEY'LL LIVE TOMORROW.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
TILL YOU FINISH YOUR VEGETABLES.
[ clock ticking ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THERE'S A BETTER WAY...
V8 V-FUSION.
VEGETABLE NUTRITION THEY NEED,
FRUIT TASTE THEY LOVE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
OR...TRY KIDS BOXES!
[ Male Announcer ]
THE WAY IT MOVES.
THE WAY IT CLEANS.
EVERYTHING ABOUT
THE ORAL-B POWER BRUSH
IS SIMPLY REVOLUTIONARY.
ORAL-B POWER BRUSHES OSCILLATE,
ROTATE
AND EVEN PULSATE
TO GENTLY LOOSEN AND BREAK UP
THAT STICKY PLAQUE
WITH MORE BRUSH MOVEMENTS
THAN MANUAL BRUSHES
AND EVEN
UP TO 50% MORE
THAN LEADING
SONIC TECHNOLOGY BRUSHES
FOR A SUPERIOR CLEAN.
ORAL-B POWER BRUSHES.
GO TO ORALB.COM
FOR THE LATEST OFFERS.
>>> ON THIS SPECIAL EDITION OF
"EARLY START," A COMMUNITY AND A
NATION IN MOURNING.
>> NEWTOWN, YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
>> THE PRESIDENT, OFFERING WORDS
OF COMFORT AND INSPIRATION TO
THOSE TRYING TO MAKE SENSE OF A
SENSELESS TRAGEDY.
>> IN THE FACE OF INDESCRIBABLE
VIOLENCE, IN THE FACE OF
UNCONSCIONABLE EVIL, YOU LOOKED
OUT FOR EACH OTHER.
AND YOU CARED FOR ONE ANOTHER.
AND YOU'VE LOVED ONE ANOTHER.
>> WE'RE REMEMBERING THE
VICTIMS, 20 CHILDREN AND 6 CHIL
ADULTS, SOME WHO GAVE THEIR
LIVES TO SAVE OTHERS.
>> SHE WAS TRULY SELF-LESS.
SHE WOULD NOT HESITATE SAVE
ANYONE ELSE BEFORE HERSELF,
ESPECIALLY CHILDREN.
>> AND MORE IMPORTANT DETAILS
EMERGE ABOUT THE WORST DAY,
PEOPLE IN THE SMALL CONNECTICUT
COMMUNITY, SEARCH FOR STRENGTH
TO FACE THE DIFFICULT DAYS
AHEAD.
>> WE WILL MOVE ON, WE WILL
NEVER FORGET, WE WILL IN MANY
WAYS BE MADE STRONGER FOR WHAT
HAS TRANSPIRED.
AND WE WILL GET BETTER.
>> GOOD MORNING, WELCOME,
EVERYBODY.
COMING TO YOU LIVE THIS MORNING
FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
I'M SOLEDAD, O'BRIEN.
>> AND I'M JOHN BERMAN.
THIS IS A SPECIAL EDITION OF
"EARLY START."
>> TODAY, IT'S STILL DARK OUT,
OF COURSE, BUT IT WILL BE A VERY
RAW AND COLD AND PRETTY
MISERABLE MORNING, NOT JUST, OF
COURSE, BECAUSE OF THE WEATHER
THIS WILL BE THE DAY THAT THE
VERY FIRST FUNERALS ARE HELD IN
THE AFTERMATH OF FRIDAY'S
MASSACRE AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
HERE IS THE LATEST THAT WE KNOW.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WAS HERE LAST
NIGHT, TRYING TO BRING SOME
COMFORT TO REALLY WHAT IS
IMPOSSIBLE TO COMFORT.
TRYING TO ASSURE THOSE WHO LOST
LOVED ONES THEY ARE NOT ALONE.
PROMISING TO USE ALL OF HIS
POWERS AS PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES TO TRY TO STOP
THESE KINDS OF TRAGEDIES AND
TODAY NEWTOWN WILL BEGIN TO BURY
ITS DEAD.
THEY WILL START WITH TWO
6-YEAR-OLD BOYS.
AND JACK PINTO, A BIG NEW YORK
GIANTS FOOTBALL FAN.
AND NOAH POSNER, LITTLEST OF ALL
OF THE VICTIMS.
>> WE ARE BEGINNING LEARN MORE
ABOUT THE VICTIMS, LIKE ANNA
MARQU
MARQUEZ GREENE, WHO LOVED TO
WRITE LOVE LETTERS TO HER
PARENTS.
HOW THE SHOOTER MADE HIS WAY
INTO THE SCHOOL AND WHY HE MAY
HAVE BEEN TARGETING SANDY HOOK
TO BEGIN WITH AND AN EXCLUSIVE,
HEART WRENCHING MOVING INTERVIEW
WITH THE FAMILY OF PRINCIPAL
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG.
WHAT HER DAUGHTERS WOULD LIKE
YOU TO KNOW ABOUT THEIR MOTHER
THE FINAL MOMENTS SHE WAS ALIVE.
>> LOTS OF TEARS AND LOTS OF
PAIN IN NEWTOWN TODAY.
SANDRA ENDO, OUTSIDE A CHURCH IN
A COMMUNITY THAT IS ABSOLUTELY
GRIEF STRICKEN.
TODAY THE PROCESS OF SAYING
GOOD-BYE BEGINS.
>> TODAY, THE FIRST OF MANY
FUNERALS TO COME IN THE DAYS
AHEAD.
LAST NIGHT, PRESIDENT OBAMA CAME
HERE TO SPEAK TO RESIDENTS TO
OFFER COMFORT, BUT ALSO HE VOWED
TO DO MORE.
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS, I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT, TO MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS, TO PARENTS
AND EDUCATORS, IN AN EFFORT
AIMED AT PREVENTING MORE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS.
>> THE PRESIDENT ALSO MET WITH
VICTIMS' FAMILY MEMBERS AT A
VIGIL LAST NIGHT AND SPOKE ABOUT
THE SPIRIT OF THIS TOWN IN THE
FACE OF SUCH TRAGEDY.
>> AS A COMMUNITY, HAVE YOU
INSPIRED US, NEWTOWN.
IN THE FACE OF INDESCRIBABLE
VIOLENCE.
IN THE FACE OF UNCONSCIONABLE
EVIL, YOU HAVE LOOKED OUT FOR
EACH OTHER.
YOU'VE CARED FOR ONE ANOTHER,
AND YOU HAVE LOVED ONE ANOTHER.
THIS IS HOW NEWTOWN WILL BE
REMEMBERED AND WITH TIME AND
GOD'S GRACE, THAT LOVE WILL SEE
YOU THROUGH.
>> NOW THIS AFTERNOON,
6-YEAR-OLD NOAH POSNER WILL IT
LAID TO REST.
ALSO LAID TO REST, JACK PINTO.
SOLEDAD.
>> QUICK QUESTION ABOUT SCHOOL'S
RETURN.
WE KNOW CONNECTICUT KIDS WILL GO
BACK OVERALL ACROSS THE STATE
TODAY, BUT FOR THESE KIDS IN
THIS SCHOOL WHICH IS STILL A
CRIME SCENE, OBVIOUSLY NOT GOING
TO HEAD BACK TO THAT SCHOOL,
WHEN DO THEY GO BACK TO SCHOOL
AND WHERE DO THEY GO BACK TO
SCHOOL?
>> ALL NEWTOWN SCHOOLS WILL BE
CLOSED TODAY AS STAFF TALKS WITH
EXPERTS TO FIGURE OUT A WAY TO
BEST DEAL WITH THE TRAGEDY FOR
THEIR STUDENTS.
TOMORROW, ALL CLASSES WILL
RESUME EXCEPT FOR SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY, THEY WILL BE
ACCOMMODATED BY A NEIGHBORING
SCHOOL IN A NEIGHBORING TOWN AS
SOON AS THEY CAN WORK OUT THE
DETAILS.
AGAIN, RESIDENTS AND COMMUNITY
MEMBERS TRYING TO GET A SENSE OF
NORMALCY BACK FOR STUDENTS WHO
HAVE SUFFERED SO MUCH.
>> SANDRA ENDO, THANK YOU FOR
THE UPDATE.
APPRECIATE IT.
JOHN.
>> OF COURSE, HERE IN
CONNECTICUT, OUR FOCUS AS MUCH
AS WE CAN IS ON THE VICTIMS, BUT
THIS IS A CRIME SCENE AND
INVESTIGATORS IN THE PAIN
STAYING PROCESS OF PIECING
TOGETHER WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
IT'S AN AROUND THE CLOCK
INVESTIGATION BY CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE, AND AS THEY GATHER
EVIDENCE, POLICE HAVE POSITIVELY
IDENTIFIED ADAM LANZA AS THE
GUNMAN WHO OPENED FIRE.
THEY ALSO CONFIRM THAT HE DID
KILL HIMSELF.
WHAT WE DON'T KNOW YET?
WHY?
WHY DID HE TARGET THE SCHOOL?
WHY DID HE TARGET THOSE INNOCENT
CHILDREN INSIDE?
ALISON KOSIK WITH THE LATEST ON
THE INVESTIGATION OUTSIDE THE
SUSPECT'S HOME.
GOOD MORNING, ALLISON.
>> GOOD MORNING, JOHN.
AND IT MAY BE A WHILE BEFORE WE
KNOW THAT MOTIVE.
AT THIS MOMENT, WE ARE GETTING A
CLOSER LOOK AT WHERE ADAM LANZA
LIVED WITH HIS MOTHER NANCY, WHO
HE ALSO SHOT AND KILLED BEFORE
HE WENT TO SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
A HOUSE, BIG HOUSE, SITTING ON
TOP OF THE HILL TO MY LEFT.
ALL THE LIGHTS ARE ON, A COUPLE
OF POLICE CARS ARE IN THE
DRIVEWAY.
WE'RE ALSO LEARNING NEW DETAILS
OF HOW THIS GUNMAN BLASTED HIS
WAY INTO THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
HOW MANY WEAPONS HE ON HIM, AND
HOW MUCH AMMUNITION HE WAS
CARRYING.
THE GUNMAN, ADAM LANZA, FIRED
DOZENS OF BULLETS, USING A SEMI
AUTOMATIC RIFLE ON HIS VICTIMS,
USING A PISTOL TO KILL HIMSELF.
>> THE VICTIM UTILIZED MOST OF
THE TIME DURING THIS HORRIFIC
CRIME, WAS IDENTIFIED A
BUSHMASTER AR-15 ASSAULT WEAPON.
IT HAD MULTIPLE MAGAZINES.
THE SUSPECT ALSO HAD A GLOCK 10
MILLIMETER, AND ONE OTHER
WEAPON.
>> A FOURTH WEAPON, A SHOTGUN
WAS FOUND IN THE CAR PARKED
OUTSIDE THE SCHOOL.
THEY CONTINUE TO FOCUS THE
EFFORT ON THE SCHOOL CRIME
SCENE, WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT
THE SHOOTER'S ACTIVITIES IN THE
DAYS, WEEKS AND MONTHS LEADING
UP TO THE SECOND WORST SCHOOL
SHOOTING IN THE NATION'S
HISTORY.
LANZA VISITED A GUN RANGE.
WE DO NOT KNOW WHERE OR WHEN.
AN ATF SPOKESPERSON SAYS HIS
MOTHER NANCY LANZA VISITED A
SHOOTING RANGE MULTIPLE TIMES.
HER SON ALSO KID HER.
AS FOR MOTIVE, AUTHORITIES ARE
SEARCHING FOR ANSWERS.
>> WE'RE PLEASED WITH THE WORK
THAT'S BEEN DONE SO FAR.
I'M HOPING THAT HELPS ANSWER
THAT QUESTION.
WE'RE PLEASED WITH THE PROGRESS
THAT WE'RE MAKING.
THIS IS A VERY LONG, TEDIOUS
PROCESS.
>> AND FEDERAL AGENTS CONTINUE
CHASING MANY LEADS, INCLUDING
VISITING AS MANY AS 30 GUN
RANGES IN THE AREA AND HUNDREDS
OF GUN SHOPS, OF GUN DEALERS IN
THE SURROUNDING AREA, AT LEAST
FOUR COUNTIES.
WHAT THEY ARE REALLY LOOKING
FORK JOHN, TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT THE GUNMAN WAS UP TO IN THE
DAYS, WEEKS, MONTHS, LEADING UP
TO THE MASSACRE ON FRIDAY.
JOHN.
>> ALISON KOSIK, OUTSIDE THE
LANZA HOME.
ONE OF THE CRIME SCENES, ONE OF
THE SITES THAT INVESTIGATORS ARE
STILL LOOKING INTO IN
CONNECTICUT.
THANK YOU, ALLISON.
>> THE SCHOOL MASSACRE HAS
REIGNITED THE GUN CONTROL DEBATE
IN AMERICA.
PRESIDENT OBAMA, INSISTING EARLY
ON THAT THERE WAS MORE
MEANINGFUL ACTION THAT NEEDED TO
BE TAKEN TO PREVENT FUTURE
TRAGEDIES, OPPONENTS OF GUN
CONTROL SAY AMERICANS HAVE THE
RIGHT TO BEAR ARMS, BUT
SUPPORTERS OF STRICTER GUN LAWS
QUESTION ANYBODY'S RIGHT TO OWN
AUTOMATIC WEAPONS.
>> THESE ARE ASSAULT WEAPONS.
YOU DON'T HUNT DEER WITH THESE
THINGS AND THAT'S THE QUESTION
THAT A LOT OF PEOPLE HAVE TO
RESOLVE THIS THEIR OWN MINDS.
WHERE SHOULD THIS LINE GET
DRAWN?
>> A FREE PEOPLE SHOULD BE AN
ARMED PEOPLE IT ENSURES AGAINST
THE TYRANNY OF THE GOVERNMENT IF
THEY KNOW THE BIGGEST ARMY IS
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE.
>> A NUMBER OF GUN CONTROL
MEASURES HAVE BEEN INTRODUCED IN
CONGRESS, BUT NOT ONE SINGLE
MEASURE HAS MADE IT TO THE FLOOR
FOR A VOTE.
AND DIANNE FEINSTEIN SAID
YESTERDAY SHE WILL INTRODUCE A
BILL THAT WILL BAN ASSAULT
WEAPONS.
COMING UP AT 6:40, WE'LL TALK
MORE ABOUT GUN CONTROL AND
WHETHER CONGRESS WILL TAKE UP
THE ISSUE AND THERE WILL BE ANY
TYPE OF CHANGE.
WE'LL TALK TO MARY BONO MACK AND
CONNIE MACK.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT MENTAL HEALTH.
A REAL PASSION FOR CONGRESSWOMAN
MACK.
>> WE JUST FINISHED A
PRESIDENTIAL CAMPAIGN 18 MONTHS
LONG, AND GUN CONTROL HARDLY
CAME UP AT ALL.
>> ALMOST NEVER.
>> NOW THAT ISSUE VERY MUCH BACK
ON THE TABLE.
TODAY, FIRST DAY THAT KIDS
RETURN TO SCHOOL ACROSS THE
COUNTRY SINCE THE CONNECTICUT
MASSACRE.
SCHOOLS ARE EXPECTED TO REVIEW
SECURITY PLANS TO SATISFY
ANXIOUS STUDENTS, PARENTS AND
TEACHERS.
I WAS RECEIVING UPDATES FROM MY
KIDS' SCHOOL ALL WEEK.
DEPARTMENTS ARE EXPECTED TO
INCREASE SCHOOL PATROLS, AND
MANY DISTRICTS OFFERING
ADDITIONAL COUNSELING SERVICES
TO STUDENTS TODAY.
>> YOU KNOW THEY NEED IT IN THE
WAKE OF THIS.
"SATURDAY NIGHT LIVE," NORMALLY
KNOWN TO TAKE KIND OF A FUNNY
AND SATIRIC LOOK IN THE NEWS, A
MUCH MORE SUBDUED APPROACH IN
THE WAKE OF THIS.
THE NEW YORK CITY CHILDREN'S
CHORUS OPENED THE SHOW SINGING
"SILENT NIGHT."
IT WAS BEAUTIFUL.
♪ SILENT NIGHT HOLY NIGHT ALL IS
CALM ALL IS BRIGHT
ROUND YON VIRGIN ♪
.
>> BRAVO, "SATURDAY NIGHT LIVE.
A BEAUTIFUL, MOVING TRIBUTE.
A QUESTION A LOT OF PEOPLE HAVE
BEEN ASKING, I'VE BEEN ASKING.
HOW TO TALK TO YOUR CHILDREN
ABOUT THE NEWTOWN SCHOOL
TRAGEDY.
WE'LL DISCUSS THAT, COMING UP
NEXT.
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU ARE A BUSINESS PRO.
OMNIPOTENT OF OPPORTUNITY.
YOU KNOW HOW TO MIX BUSINESS...
WITH BUSINESS.
AND YOU...RENT FROM NATIONAL.
BECAUSE ONLY NATIONAL LETS YOU
CHOOSE ANY CAR IN THE AISLE.
AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE A FULL-SIZE
OR ABOVE.
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
I COULD GET USED TO THIS.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, YOU COULD BUSINESS PRO.
YES, YOU COULD.
GO NATIONAL. GO LIKE A PRO.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
BECAUSE FOR EVERY TWO POUNDS
YOU LOSE
THROUGH DIET AND EXERCISE,
ALLI CAN HELP YOU
LOSE ONE MORE
BY BLOCKING
SOME OF THE FAT YOU EAT.
LET'S FIGHT FAT WITH ALLI.
♪
(Announcer) When Subaru owners
look in the mirror,
they see more than themselves.
So we celebrate our year-end
with the "share the love" event.
Get a great deal on a new Subaru
and 250 dollars goes to your
choice of five charities.
By the end of this, our fifth
year,
our total can reach almost 25
million dollars.
It's a nice reflection on us
all.
Now through January 2nd.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYONE, TO A
SPECIAL EDITION OF "EARLY
START," AS NEWTOWN AND THE
ENTIRE NATION GRIEVES THIS
MORNING.
WE ARE EXAMINING HOW THE TRAGEDY
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
MAYBE COULD HAVE BEEN PREVENTED.
>> WE HAVE THE HEAD OF COLUMBIA
UNIVERSITY'S NATIONAL CENTER FOR
DISASTER PREPAREDNESS, ALSO
PRESIDENT AND COFOUNDER OF THE
CHILDREN'S HEALTH FUND.
ARE YOU OFTEN BROUGHT IN AFTER
DISASTERS, SPENT A LOT OF TIME
AT KATRINA, BP OIL SPILL,
HURRICANE SANDY AS WELL.
IN THIS PARTICULAR CASE AT THIS
PARTICULAR SCHOOL, THEY DID
EVERYTHING RIGHT.
>> THIS IS AN AMAZINGLY PREPARED
FACULTY AND ADMINISTRATION OF
THIS SCHOOL, AND WE WERE VERY
IMPRESSED.
I WAS EXPECTING TO SEE, YOU
KNOW, CHAOS, DISORGANIZATION, SO
FORTH.
WHAT WE SAW INSTEAD WAS HEROISM,
AND A REALLY DEFINED PLAN OF
ACTION THAT EITHER CAME BECAUSE
PEOPLE KNEW WHAT THEY WERE DOING
AND FIGURED IT OUT ON THE SPOT,
BUT A LOT OF THIS WAS PRACTICE
BEFOREHAND WHICH IS REALLY
CRITICAL.
AND I THINK THE TEACHERS DESERVE
A TREMENDOUS AMOUNT OF CREDIT AS
OBVIOUSLY DOES THE
ADMINISTRATION.
AND THE STUDENTS FOR THAT
MATTER.
>> THEY HAD TRAINED.
THEY HAD TRAINED IN THESE
EXERCISES FOR THESE TYPES OF
EVENTS.
>> YEAH.
THIS IS THE KIND OF THING WE
WOULD HOPE TO SEE IN EVERY
SCHOOL IN THE COUNTRY THAT THE
SCHOOLS ARE PREPARED FOR ALL
KINDS OF EMERGENCIES.
THIS PARTICULAR THING, SO
POWERFULLY DANGEROUS, AND VERY
IMPORTANT THAT PEOPLE ARE
KEEPING THEIR PLANS, FOLLOWING A
PLAN, KNOW WHAT TO DO.
KEEPING THINGS UNDER CONTROL AS
MUCH AS POSSIBLE UNDER THE WORST
POSSIBLE CIRCUMSTANCES.
>> WE CREATED THE LOCKDOWN
SCENARIO AFTER COLUMBINE AND
PART OF THAT, BECAUSE HAD YOU
TEENAGE SHOOTERS AND TEENAGERS
IN THE SCHOOLS AND THE IDEA, IF
YOU HAD INSTEAD OF CHAOS OF
EVERYONE IN THE HALLWAYS, PEOPLE
COULDN'T EXPECT WHO WAS A
SUSPECT AND WHO WAS A STUDENT
WHO NEEDED HELP.
VERY CHAOTIC.
I WONDER IF SCHOOLS NEED TO GO
FURTHER IN SOME CAPACITY.
A LOT OF THOSE CHILDREN, YOU
WOULD HEAR THE PARENTS DESCRIBE
IT AS IF THEY WERE IN LOCKDOWN
IN A CLASSROOM AND STUCK THERE.
HOW CAN YOU MAKE A SCHOOL
PHYSICALLY SAFER?
>> FIRST OF ALL, THERE ARE
NUMBER OF THINGS YOU CAN CONTROL
ACCESS INTO THE SCHOOL.
STEP NUMBER ONE.
AND THIS SCHOOL DID A PRETTY
GOOD JOB.
ALL SORTS OF PROCEDURES FOR
GETTING INTO THE SCHOOL.
THIS IS A SHOOTER, AS WE KNOW,
FORCED HIMSELF INTO THE SCHOOL
UNDER A VERY VIOLENT SITUATION.
I DON'T THINK THERE WAS MUCH
MORE THEY COULD HAVE DONE ABOUT
IT.
WE WILL SEE A LOT OF DISCUSSION,
CONTROVERSY, ON WHETHER WE NEED
TO DO MORE ABOUT THAT.
WHETHER ANYBODY NEEDS TO BE
ARMED IN THE SCHOOL WHICH I
CERTAINLY WOULD OPPOSE
PERSONALLY, BUT ON THE OTHER
HAND, MANY SCHOOLS IN VIRGINIA,
FAIRFAX COUNTY, HIGH SCHOOLS AND
JUNIOR HIGH SCHOOLS WHO HAVE
POLICE OFFICERS, PUBLIC SAFETY
OFFICER WHO'S ARE THERE, WHERE
THERE IS A PHYSICAL PRESENCE, AS
A REASSURING PRESENCE, MAY OR
MAY NOT BE A FOOD IDEA.
A LOT OF THINGS NOW WILL BE
EXPLORED.
WE'RE REALLY IN UNCHARTERED
TERRITORY NOW.
NOW ABSOLUTELY NO-MAN'S LAND IN
TERMS OF UNDERSTANDING WHAT
NEEDS TO BE DONE.
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SITUATION.
ONE EXAMPLE IN 2006 WHERE THE
SCHOOL IN LANCASTER,
PENNSYLVANIA, WAS INVADED, AND A
LOT OF CHILDREN WERE MASSACRED
THERE AND NOTHING MUCH HAPPENED.
WITH THIS EVENT, I THINK WE'LL
SEE SOME ACTION, A LOT OF
DISCUSSION ABOUT WHAT WE'LL DO
NEXT IN TERMS OF PROTECTING
CHILDREN AND DON'T FORGET, THIS
IS A VERY, VERY RARE OCCURRENCE.
>> LET ME PLAY A LITTLE OF WHAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID IN THE
VIGIL.
I THOUGHT IT WAS A BEAUTIFUL,
VERY EMOTIONAL VIGIL LAST NIGHT.
LET'S PLAY A LITTLE OF WHAT THE
PRESIDENT SAID.
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS, I WILL
USE WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE
HOLDS TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW
CITIZENS, FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT,
TO MENTAL HEALTH PROFESSIONALS
TO PARENTS AND EDUCATORS, IN AN
EFFORT AIMED AT PREVENTING MORE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS.
>> HE BASICALLY SAID WE HAVE TO
ENGAGE EVERYBODY IN FINDING A
SOLUTION TO THIS, AND HE
MENTIONED MENTAL HEALTH AS WELL.
THERE IS THIS INTERSECTION
BETWEEN ACCESS TO GUNS WHICH THE
KILLER RELIED ON HEAVILY IN THIS
CASE, AND ALSO WE KNOW
DESCRIPTIONS OF HIM BEING
DISTURBED.
ANYONE WHO COMMITS A MASS
MURDER, THAT'S FAIR TO SAY, AND
OTHER INFORMATION COMING UP
ABOUT HIS CHILDHOOD AS WELL.
WHAT -- WHAT SHOULD THE FOCUS BE
ON MENTAL HEALTH?
WHICH PEOPLE DON'T DISCUSS VERY
MUCH UNTIL THERE IS SOME KIND OF
TRAGEDY LIKE THIS?
>> FIRST OF ALL, THERE ARE
MILLIONS AND MILLIONS OF PEOPLE
THAT HAVE ALL SORTS OF MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES FROM ANXIETY AND
STRESS TO MUCH MORE SERIOUS
DISORDERS.
THERE IS THE WHOLE SPECTRUM,
AUTISM SPECTRUM, MANY, MANY
ISSUES, ALL OF US KNOW PEOPLE,
WE HAVE ISSUES.
>> NO CORRELATION BETWEEN
AUTISM --
>> THAT'S WHAT I WAS GOING TO
SAY.
NO CORRELATION BETWEEN AUTISM OR
THE AUTISM SPECTRUM WITH THIS
KIND OF VIOLENT BEHAVIOR.
SO ALL I'M SAYING, WE HAVE A
GREAT MIX OF ALL KINDS OF ISSUES
WE HAVE TO DEAL WITH IN SOCIETY
AND A LOT OF GUNS, AND YOU HAVE
SOMEBODY THAT GETS TO THAT
TIPPING POINT, FOR WHATEVER
REASONS, AND THERE ARE -- THESE
KINDS OF WEAPONS AVAILABLE, WE
HAVE A TOXIC STEW PROBLEMS, AND
THOSE WHO BECOME SHOOTERS IS
VIRTUALLY IMPOSSIBLE.
I MEAN, A LOT OF WARNING SIGNS
THAT PEOPLE NEED TO GET MENTAL
HEALTH -- MENTAL HEALTH
ASSISTANCE AND PROFESSIONAL HELP
AND IN TERMS OF PICKING UP
INDIVIDUALS BECOME VIOLENT
SHOOTERS LIKE THIS, IT'S VERY,
VERY CHALLENGING.
>> DOCTOR, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WE APPRECIATE YOUR TIME.
>> GONE MUCH TOO SOON OBVIOUSLY.
THE VICTIMS OF THE HORRIBLE,
HORRIBLE SHOOTING.
BUT NOT FORGOTTEN, WHEN WE COME
BACK, WE'LL TAKE A CLOSER LOOK
AT THE VICTIMS WHO LOST THEIR
LIVES IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
E!
A SHOOTING STAR!
MAKE A WISH!
I WISH WE COULD
LIE HERE FOREVER.
I WISH THIS TEST DRIVE WAS OVER,
SO WE COULD HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
TEST DRIVE!
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A JETTA.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN,
$0 DUE AT SIGNING, $0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
ALRIWOAH! DID YOU GET THAT?
AND...FLIP!
YEP, LOOK AT THIS. IT TAKES
LIKE 20 PICTURES AT A TIME. I
NEVER MISS ANYTHING.
ISN'T THAT AWESOME?
UH THAT'S REALLY COOL.
YOU SHOULD UPLOAD THESE.
I KNOW, RIGHT?
THAT IS REALLY AMAZING.
THE PICTURES ARE SO CLEAR.
KEVIN'S A HANDSOME DEVIL
THAT PHONE DOES EVERYTHING!
SEARCH DOG TRICKS.
OKAY, SEE IF WE CAN TEACH
HIM SOMETHING COOL.
LOOK AT HOW LAZY KEVIN IS.
KEVIN, GET IT TOGETHER DUDE
CMON, KEVIN
TAKE 20 PICTURES WITH BURST
SHOT ON THE GALAXY S3.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYONE.
WE'RE IN A GRAY, RAINY NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, THIS MORNING.
GRAY IN SO MANY WAYS.
A GRIEVING COMMUNITY PREPARES
FOR THE FIRST OF MORE THAN TWO
DOZEN FUNERALS.
TODAY, THEY BURY TWO 6-YEAR-OLD
BOYS, JACK PINTO, A BIG NEW YORK
GIANTS FOOTBALL FANS, AND NOAH
POZNER, THE YOUNGEST OF THE
VICTIMS.
>> A BRUTAL DAY.
POLICE ARE STILL TRYING TO PUT
TOGETHER THE PIECES OF WHAT
EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED.
AN ONGOING INVESTIGATION.
LOTS OF QUESTIONS.
VERY LITTLE INFORMATION IS KNOWN
ABOUT THE SHOOTER AND WHY HE
MIGHT BE TARGETING THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND WHY
THIS COMMUNITY WOULD BE A FOCUS
OF HIS RAGE.
>> SO MANY QUESTIONS, AND THE
INVESTIGATION DOES CONTINUE.
A LOT OF OTHER NEWS IN THE WORLD
THIS MORNING.
OTHER TOP STORIES, WE'LL GO TO
CHRISTINE ROMANS IN NEW YORK.
>>> KILLED IN THE LINE OF DUTY.
TWO KANSAS CITY POLICE OFFICERS.
SHOT WHILE REPORTING TO A
SUSPICIOUS CAR AT A GROCERY
STORE.
THEY DIED LASTNIGHT AT TOPEKA
HOSPITAL.
A THIRD OFFICER ON THE SCENE NOT
HIT.
THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER,
22-YEAR-OLD DAVID TISCARENO ON
THE RUN, CONSIDERED ARMED AND
EXTREMELY DANGEROUS.
>>> THE STATE DEPARTMENT IS
EXPECTED TO GET THE RESULTS OF
AN INDEPENDENT REVIEW BOARD
INVESTIGATION ON THE TERROR
ATTACK AT THE U.S. CONSULATE IN
BENGHAZI.
HEARINGS AND TESTIMONY IN THE
HOUSE AND SENATE BEGIN ON
THURSDAY.
>>> SENATOR JOHN KERRY, EXPECTED
TO BE PRESIDENT OBAMA'S PICK TO
BE THE NEXT SECRETARY OF STATE.
ACCORDING TO A DEMOCRATIC
SOURCE, A FORMAL ANNOUNCEMENT
COULD COME NEXT WEEK.
HIS CURRENT ROLE AS CHAIR OF THE
SENATE FOREIGN RELATIONS
COMMITTEE, KERRY HAS TRAVELED
THE WORLD TO SOOTHE STRAINED
RELATIONS, INCLUDING TRAVELING
TO PAKISTAN AFTER THE DEATH OF
OSAMA BIN LADEN.
>>> ALL EYES ON WASHINGTON TO
SEE IF LAWMAKERS CAN STRIKE A
DEAL TO AVOID TAX INCREASES AND
SPENDING CUTS.
>>> AND IN JAPAN, THE NIKKEI IS
TRADING HIGHER.
DESPITE ECONOMIC UPBEAT DATA ON
THE GLOBAL ECONOMY, U.S. MARKETS
ENDED LOWER.
>>> CAN U.S. BE MAKING STRIDES
IN THE FISCAL CLIFF
NEGOTIATIONS?
JOHN BOEHNER HAS OFFERED TO
EXTEND THE DEBT LIMIT FOR A YEAR
AS PART OF THE DEFICIT REDUCTION
DEAL.
THE DEBT LIMIT STANDS AT 16$16.
TRILLION.
RAISING IT FURTHER REQUIRES AN
ACT OF CONGRESS, SOMETHING
REPUBLICANS STRONGLY OPPOSE.
BOEHNAIOEHNER PROPOSED HIGHER T
RATES FOR THOSE AMERICANS MAKING
MORE THAN $1 MILLION.
THE PRESIDENT WOULD LIKE TO
RAISE TAXES ON THOSE EARNING
$250,000.
>> STILL A BIT OF A GAP OF WHAT
THEY ARE POSITIVE POSING AND
WHAT THE PRESIDENT WANTS.
>> A LOT OF PEOPLE SAY THE
TRAGEDY HERE MAY MAKE A DEAL
HAPPEN MORE QUICKLY.
NO ONE WANTS TO BE SEEN AS PETTY
OR PLAYING PETTY POLITICS AFTER
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
IT JUST DOESN'T FIT.
>> THROUGHOUT THE MORNING, WE'LL
TELL YOU MORE ABOUT THE VICTIMS
OF THE NEWTOWN SCHOOL SHOOTING.
EACH FALLEN CHILD, EVERY ADULT
WHO PERISHED.
ZORAIDA SAMBOLIN HAS A LOOK AT
THAT THIS MORNING.
>> THANK YOU, SOLEDAD.
WE'RE REMEMBERING DYLAN HUOCKLE
THIS MORNING.
ONLY 6 YEARS OLD.
HIS MOM DESCRIBED THE AREA AS A
WONDERFUL PLACE TO LIVE WITH
INCREDIBLE NEIGHBORS AND
WONDERFUL SCHOOLS.
THEN THERE IS 6-YEAR-OLD
MADELINE HSU.
LITTLE MADY, AND A NEIGHBOR WHO
SHARED RIDES TO SCHOOL REMEMBERS
HER AS A SWEET AND WONDERFUL
GIRL.
WE'RE REMEMBERING CATHERINE
VIOLET HUBBARD, SHE LOVES N S
ANIMALS, AND INSTEAD OF FLOWERS,
HER FAMILY REQUESTS DONATIONS TO
THE NEWTOWN ANIMAL SHELTER.
CHASE COW WA
KOWALSKKI LOVED SPORTS, AND
JESSE LEWIS LEARNING TO RIDE A
HORSE.
TWO MINIATURES, THREE DOGS AND A
FLOCK OF CHICKENS.
HIS MOTHER SAID HE LOVED TO TELL
STORIES AND LIVED LIFE BRAVE,
AND HE LIVED LIFE TRUE.
COMING UP, MUCH MORE LIVE FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WHERE THE
NATION LOOKED TO PRESIDENT OBAMA
FOR COMFORT LAST NIGHT AND WHERE
DETECTIVES CONTINUE TO LOOK FOR
ANSWERS TODAY.
[ Female Announcer ]
WHAT IF THE NEXT BIG THING,
ISN'T A THING AT ALL?
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
♪
BECOMING
PART OF THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
TREES WILL TALK TO NETWORKS
WILL TALK TO SCIENTISTS
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE.
CARS WILL TALK TO ROAD SENSORS
WILL TALK TO STOPLIGHTS
ABOUT TRAFFIC EFFICIENCY.
THE AMBULANCE WILL TALK
TO PATIENT RECORDS
WILL TALK TO DOCTORS
ABOUT SAVING LIVES.
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
THE NEXT BIG THING?
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
♪
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
♪
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
WITH TWO TIMES THE POINTS
ON DINING IN RESTAURANTS,?
YOU MAY FIND
YOURSELF ASKING
WHY NOT, A LOT.
CHASE SAPPHIRE PREFERRED.
THERE'S MORE TO ENJOY.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME FOR CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
>>> AND MUST KNOW THAT WHATEVER
MEASURE OF COMFORT WE CAN
PROVIDE, WE WILL PROVIDE.
WHATEVER PORTION OF SADNESS THAT
WE CAN SHARE WITH YOU TO EASE
THIS HEAVY LOAD, WE WILL GLADLY
BEAR IT.
NEWTOWN, YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
>> THAT WAS PRESIDENT OBAMA FROM
LAST NIGHT, YOU CAN HEAR HIM
OFFERING COMFORT TO A GRIEVING
COMMUNITY.
NEWTOWN PREPARES TO BEGIN
BURYING THE VICTIMS OF THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SHOOTING.
THAT WILL HAPPEN TODAY.
WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
SOLEDAD O'BRIEN, LIVE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT THIS
MORNING.
>> I'M JOHN BERMAN THIS IS A
SPECIAL EDITION OF "EARLY
START."
>> I'M ZORAIDA SAMBOLIN.
AT THE MEDIA BRIEFING LOCATION.
AT NEWTOWN, POLICE TALKED TO
REPORT
REPORTERS IN ABOUT TWO HOURS.
WE'LL CONTINUE TO MONITOR THAT.
>> ZORAIDA, THANK YOU.
THE POLICE HAVE BEEN REALLY GOOD
ON THE INVESTIGATION AND ALSO
HOW THE FAMILIES ARE DOING.
A CLOSE-KNIT, SMALL COMMUNITY.
THEY ARE STILL REELING AND NUMB.
THREE DAYS SINCE THE SENSELESS
MASSACRE TOOK PLACE AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL FRIDAY
MORNING.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA PAID A VISIT
LAST NIGHT.
COMFORTING FAMILY MEMBERS IN
PRIVATE AND PUBLICLY ASSURING
THEM YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
HE PROMISED TO USE ALL OF HIS
POWERS AS PRESIDENT TO STOP
THESE KINDS OF TRAGEDIES.
REMAINS TO BE SEEN WHAT THAT
MEANS EXACTLY.
TODAY, NEWTOWN BEGINS BURYING
ITS DEAD, STARTING WITH TWO
6-YEAR-OLD BOYS.
JACK PINTO, LOVED NEW YORK
GIANTS AND NOAH POZNER, THE
YOUNGEST VICTIM, SHOT 11 TIMES.
>> EVERY TIME YOU LOOK AT THESE
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE BOYS, BREAKS
YOUR HEART ALL OVER AGAIN.
>> IT LOOKS LIKE MY BOYS, BREAKS
ME UP.
>> CAN'T THINK OF YOUR OWN KIDS
OR NIECES OR NEPHEWS OR
GRANDCHILDREN.
SO MANY QUESTIONS REMAIN IN THIS
INVESTIGATION.
HOW EXACTLY THE SHOOTER MADE HIS
WAY AROUND THE SCHOOL, WHY WOULD
HE TARGET AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
DID HE HAVE A CONNECTION TO THIS
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL?
AND, OF COURSE, THE FAMILY OF
THE PRINCIPAL SPEAKING.
>> BROKENHEARTED FAMILY OF
PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG SPOKE
LAST NIGHT.
AND A GRIPPING INTERVIEW WITH
OUR GARY TUCHMAN.
>> SO WE'RE GOING TO BRING THAT
INTERVIEW TO YOU LATER THIS
MORNING.
IT IS ABSOLUTELY HEARTBREAKING.
I FEEL IT'S A WORD WE'RE
OVERUSING, BECAUSE WE SAY IT ALL
THE TIME.
BUT I DON'T KNOW WHAT OTHER
WORDS TO USE AS YOU TRY TO
DESCRIBE PEOPLE'S GRIEF.
EVEN THE PEOPLE WHO TELL THE
STORY OF THE CHILDREN RUNNING
OUT OF THE CLASSROOM SURVIVING
AND SO HAPPY BECAUSE THEIR
CHILDREN ARE ALIVE, AND YET THEY
ARE SO GRIEF STRICKEN, BECAUSE
THEIR CHILDREN'S CLASSMATES ARE
NOT.
>> THIS IS A COMMUNITY ALL
WEEKEND WHO HAS BEEN GOING
THROUGH THIS TOGETHER.
SANDRA ENDOIN A CHURCH IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, THE
PROCESS OF SAYING GOOD-BYE,
SAND
SANDRA, ABOUT TO BEGIN TODAY.
>> ABSOLUTELY, JOHN.
THIS GROVE-STRICKEN COMMUNITY
NOW IN THE PROCESS OF LAYING
THEIR LOVED ONES TO REST.
TODAY, THE FIRST OF MANY
FUNERALS IN THE DAYS TO COME.
COMFORT AND SUPPORT FROM
PRESIDENT OBAMA TO THE RESIDENTS
OF NEWTOWN.
WITHOUT MENTIONING SPECIFICS, HE
VOWED TO DO MORE.
>> I'LL USE WHATEVER POWER THIS
OFFICE HOLDS TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW
CITIZENS, FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT
TO MENTAL HEALTH PROFESSIONALS,
TO PARENTS AND EDUCATORS, IN AN
EFFORT AIMED AT PREVENTING MORE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS.
>> Reporter: THE PRESIDENT
ATTENDED A VIGIL, WITH VICTIMS'
FAMILY MEMBERS, TO OFFER
CONDOLENCES FROM AN ENTIRE
NATION.
>> I AM VERY MINDFUL THAT MERE
WORDS CANNOT MATCH THE DEPTHS OF
YOUR SORROW, NOR CAN THEY HEAL
YOUR WOUNDED HEARTS.
I CAN ONLY HOPE IT HELPS FOR YOU
TO KNOW THAT YOU ARE NOT ALONE
IN YOUR GRIEF.
>> BUT THE GROVE STRICKIEF STRI
COMMUNITY NOW HAS THE
HEARTBREAKING TASK OF LAYING
LOVED ONES TO REST.
TODAY, THE FIRST FUNERALS.
THIS AFTERNOON 6-YEAR-OLD NOAH
POZNER WILL BE LAID TO REST.
HE HAS A TWIN SISTER WHO FAMILY
MEMBERS SAY STILL DOESN'T KNOW
THE EXACT WAY HER BROTHER DIED.
ALSO BEING BURIED, 6-YEAR-OLD
JACK PINTO, A HUGE SPORTS FAN.
HIS IDOL, STAR RECEIVER VICTOR
CRUZ.
CRUZ PAID TRIBUTE TO PINTO,
WRITING JACK PINTO, MY HERO ON
HIS CLEAT, AND ON THE OTHER,
REST IN PEACE JACK PINTO.
ALL NEWTOWN SCHOOLS WILL BE
CLOSED TODAY FOR STAFF TO WORK
WITH EXPERTS ON HOW BEST TO DEAL
WITH STUDENTS IN THE AFTERMATH.
ADMINISTRATORS ARE WORKING OUT A
PLAN WITH A NEIGHBORING TOWN TO
ACCOMMODATE SANDY HOOK STUDENTS
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
THE IMPACT ON SCHOOLS EXTENDS
FAR BEYOND THIS COMMUNITY.
SCHOOLS ACROSS THE COUNTRY WILL
LIKELY BE REVISITING THEIR
SECURITY PLANS AND HAVE TO DEAL
WITH STUDENTS' QUESTIONS THAT
MAY BE UNANSWERABLE.
JOHN.
>> SO, SANDRA, KIDS IN
CONNECTICUT GOING BACK TO SCHOOL
TODAY.
WHAT ARE THE PLANS HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT?
WHAT ARE THE PLANS FOR THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL?
>> WELL, SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
STUDENTS WILL NOT BE GOING BACK
TO SCHOOL UNTIL THEY CAN BE
ACCOMMODATED BY A NEIGHBORING
TOWN SCHOOL.
AND ALL SCHOOLS IN NEWTOWN WILL
BE CLOSED SO STAFF CAN TALK TO
EXPERTS ON HOW TO DEAL WITH THIS
TRAGEDY AND TALK TO STUDENTS
AFTER THEY DO RETURN.
CLASSES ARE TO RESUME TOMORROW.
>> SANDRA, THANKS SO MUCH.
>> HOW DO YOU TELL YOUR CHILD
WHOSE TWIN BROTHER WAS KILLED?
>> I AM THE PARENTS OF TWINS.
EVERY TIME I HEAR IT, IT'S A
PUNCH IN THE GUT.
THEY WERE SEPARATED, SO THIS
LITTLE GIRL DOESN'T KNOW HOW HER
BROTHER DIED.
>> INVESTIGATORS DESCRIBED IT AS
PEELING BACK THE LAYERS OF AN
ONION.
A PAINSTAKING PROCESS.
CONNECTICUT POLICE SAY THEY
DON'T KNOW, CERTAINLY HAVEN'T
REVEALED THE MOTIVE OF
SHOOTINGS, LOTS OF EVIDENCE.
AND EVIDENCE GATHERING
CONTINUES.
WE ARE LEARNING MOANY MORE KEY
DETAILS.
THE GUNMAN, POSITIVELY
IDENTIFIED.
SHOT HIS WAY INTO THE SCHOOL.
BASICALLY USED THE HIGH-POWERED
ASSAULT RIFLE TO BLOW THROUGH.
>> SHOT THROUGH THE GLASS.
>> MORE TO KNOW ABOUT THE
SHOOTER THAT IS NOT KNOWN.
ALISON KOSIK WITH THE LATEST ON
THE INVESTIGATION IN NEWTOWN.
ALISON.
>> THE GUNMAN LIVED IN A QUIET,
AFFLUENT NEIGHBORHOOD.
A BIG HOUSE ON TOP OF A HILL.
RIGHT NOW, THE LIGHTS ARE ON,
TWO POLICE CARS IN THE DRIVEWAY.
YOU TALKED ABOUT HOW HE
LITERALLY BLASTED HIS WAY INTO
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
ONCE HE WAS INSIDE, POLICE SAY
WHAT HE DID, HE CONCENTRATED HIS
SHOOTING ON TWO CLASSROOMS AND
IN THE HALLWAY.
POLICE SAY HE HAD THREE WEAPONS
ON HIM.
INSIDE THE SCHOOL IS WHAT THEY
FOUND, HE HAD -- HE FIRED DOZENS
OF BULLETS, USING A SEMI
AUTOMATIC RIFLE ON MOST OF HIS
VICTIMS, USING A HANDGUN TO KILL
HIMSELF.
>> THE WEAPON THAT WAS UTILIZED
MOST OF THE TIME DURING THIS
HORRIFIC CRIME WAS IDENTIFIED AS
A BUSHMASTER AR-15 ASSAULT TYPE
WEAPON.
IT HAD HIGH CAPACITY MAGAZINES.
IN ADDITION TO THAT THE SUBJECT
HAD IN HIS POSSESSION A GLOCK 10
METER, A SIG SAUER .9
MILLIMETER.
ALL WEAPONS HAD ADDITIONAL
AMMUNITION.
THE FOURTH WEAPON, A SHOTGUN
RECOVERED FROM THE SUSPECT'S
VEHICLE OUTSIDE OF THE SCHOOL.
>> WHAT'S REALLY DEVASTATING.
YOU THINK ABOUT HOW MUCH
AMMUNITION THIS GUNMAN HAD ON
HIM.
HUNDREDS OF BULLETS WITH HIM
THAT WEREN'T EVEN USED.
SOLEDAD.
>> ALISON KOSIK FOR US, OUTSIDE
THE GUNMAN'S HOME THAT HE SHARED
WITH HIS MOTHER, BOTH NOW
DECEASED.
LET'S GET BACK TO ZORAIDA
SAMBOLIN WITH MORE INFORMATION
IN THE WAKE OF THE SHOOTING.
ZORAIDA.
>> I DO, SOLEDAD.
ACTUALLY, I'M AT TREADWELL PARK,
WHERE MOST OF THE PRESS
CONFERENCES TAKE PLACE.
I WANT TO POINT SOMETHING OUT
BEHIND ME, IS A SOCCER FIELD.
YOU HAVE TO WONDER HOW MANY KIDS
AND FAMILIES ENJOYED TIME HERE.
WE WANT TO LEARN A LITTLE MORE
ABOUT THESE KIDS.
WE FIND OUT MORE ABOUT THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SHOOTINGS
AND VICTIMS.
AND WE'RE LEARNING OF ACTS OF
HEROISM VICTIMS, INCLUDING SANDY
HOOK PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG.
THEIR FAMILY SPOKE EXCLUSIVELY
WITH CNN'S GARY TUCHMAN.
THEY ARE DEVASTATED, BUT PROUD.
>> DAWN PUT HERSELF IN JEOPARDY
AND I HAVE BEEN ANGRY ABOUT
THAT.
ANGRY, UNTIL JUST NOW TODAY,
WHEN I MET THE TWO WOMEN THAT
SHE TOLD TO GO RUN TO SHELTER,
WHILE SHE ACTUALLY CONFRONTED
THE GUNMAN AND SHE COULD NOT --
SHE COULD HAVE AVOIDED THAT AND
SHE DIDN'T.
I KNEW THEY WOULDN'T.
>> I DON'T THINK I WANT TO ASK
YOU THIS.
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY TO YOUR MOM
RIGHT NOW?
>> COME BACK.
JUST COME BACK.
>> JUST BREAKS YOUR HEART.
DAWN'S DAUGHTER SAYS HER MOTHER
WAS HER ROCK, AND NOW THEIR
HERO.
THE NEWTOWN TRAGEDY WAS FELT ALL
ACROSS THE NFL ON SUNDAY AS
WELL.
NEW YORK GIANTS WIDE RECEIVER
VICTOR CRUZ HONORED ONE OF THE
VICTIMS, LITTLE 6-YEAR-OLD JACK
PINTO.
WRITING JACK WINTER YORK MY
HERO.
AND THEY WORRY SHE ON HELMETS
FOR SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
CRUZ SPOKE WITH THE BOY'S FAMILY
AFTER LEARNING THEIR BOY WAS A
BIG FAN.
THEY ARE CONSIDERING BURYING
THEIR SON IN CRUZ' JERSEY.
A REALLY EMOTIONAL MOMENT.
CRUZ WANTED TO BE ABLE TO
SOMEHOW EXPRESS HIS CONDOLENCES,
JOHN AND SOLEDAD, SO HE CALLED
THE FAMILY AND YOU KNOW, TRYING
TO FIGURE OUT WHAT HE ALSO CAN
DO TO HELP.
A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE FEELING THAT
WAY ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
>> I THINK THAT'S VERY TRUE.
VERY HARD -- WHAT DO YOU DO.
YOU LOOK AT PICTURES OF THE KIDS
AND FEEL VERY POWERLESS.
>> UNITED WAY, OTHER PLACES HAVE
SET UP CHARITIES TO SEND MONEY,
BUT PEOPLE WANT TO DO MORE THAN
THAT.
THANKS, ZORAIDA.
>>> NOT A HOT TOPIC DURING THE
2012 CAMPAIGN.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
IT WASN'T A TOPIC AT ALL.
BUT NOW GUN CONTROL IS A TOPIC.
WE'LL SPEAK WITH MARY BONO MACK
AND CONNIE MACK, BOTH HERE
TOGETHER WHEN WE COME BACK.
SO, THIS BOARD
GIVES ME RATES FOR
PROGRESSIVE DIRECT AND OTHER
CAR INSURANCE COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
CALL OR CLICK TODAY.
A Hybrid? Most are
just no fun to drive.
Now, here's one that will
make you feel alive.
Meet the five-passenger
Ford C-MAX Hybrid.
C-MAX says ha.
C-MAX says wheeee.
Which is what you get,
don't you see?
Cause C-MAX has lots more
horsepower than Prius v,
a hybrid that C-MAX
also bests in MPG.
Say hi to the all-new 47
combined MPG C-MAX Hybrid.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
>>> IN THE AFTERMATH OF THE
TRAGEDY HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WE ARE HEARING TWO
FAMILIAR ARGUMENTS RENEWED,
REALLY THROUGHOUT THE COUNTRY,
OVER GUN CONTROL AND THE STATE
OF AMERICA'S MENTAL HEALTH
SYSTEM.
COLORADO GOVERNOR JOHN
HICKENLOOPER WHO ENDURED ITS OWN
MASSACRE AT A THEATER IN AURORA
TOLD CNN'S "STATE OF THE UNION"
THIS.
WHAT YOU CAN DO IS EXPAND YOUR
CAPACITY, YOUR FRAMEWORK WITHIN
A STATE OR IN THE COUNTRY TO
HAVE MORE PEOPLE PAYING
ATTENTION AND TRYING TO DETECT
FOLKS THAT ARE UNSTABLE, ON THE
VERGE OF REAL TROUBLE, TRYING TO
CATCH THEM AT A SOONER LEVEL.
>> CALIFORNIA CONGRESSWOMAN,
MARY BONO MACK HAS CONCERNS
ABOUT THE MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEM.
WE'RE ALSO JOINED BY HER
HUSBAND, FLORIDA CONGRESSMAN
CONNIE MACK.
BOTH ARE LEAVING CONGRESS WHEN
THIS TERM IS UP.
I WANT TO TALK ABOUT MENTAL
HEALTH.
FIRST, I WANT TO TALK ABOUT THE
PRESIDENT LAST NIGHT AT THIS
VIGIL.
HE DID SPEAK ABOUT MEASURES THAT
SOUNDED LIKE HE WAS TALKING
ABOUT GUN CONTROL.
LET'S TAKE A LISTEN TO WHAT HE
SAID.
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS I HAD USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT, TO MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS, TO PARENTS
AND EDUCATORS, IN AN EFFORT
AIMED AT PREVENTING MORE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS.
>> SO WHAT CAN BE DONE TO
PREVENT THESE TRAGEDIES?
>> I THINK THE PRESIDENT IS ON
THE RIGHT PATH HERE.
THERE HAS TO BE AN AWFUL LOT
THAT IS DONE.
TO SIMPLY THROW OUT ONE QUICK
ANSWER IS NOT DOING JUSTICE TO
ANY OF THE VICTIMS AND THEIR
FAMILIES RIGHT NOW.
WE HAVE TO LOOK AT MENTAL
HEALTH.
I THINK THE QUESTION OF GUN
CONTROL, OF COURSE, WE SHOULD
DEBATE THAT QUESTION.
THERE IS GOING TO BE SO MUCH WE
REALLY HAVE TO DELVE INTO AND
NOT LOOK FOR THE QUICK, QUICK,
QUICK FIX.
>> I THINK THAT EVERYONE IS
WILLING, ABLE, AND EAGER TO TALK
ABOUT THE FULL RANGE OF ISSUES
RIGHT NOW.
ONE OF THE THINGS THE PRESIDENT
SAID LAST NIGHT, ONE OF THE MOST
INTERESTING QUESTIONS, I HAVE
BEEN ASKING MYSELF, HAVE WE DONE
EVERYTHING WE CAN TO KEEP OUR
KIDS SAFE?
HE SAID WHEN HE SEARCHED HIS OWN
FEELINGS, THE ANSWER WAS NO.
LET ME ASK YOU THIS, CONGRESSMAN
MACK, HAVE YOU BEEN DOING
EVERYTHING YOU CAN TO KEEP
AMERICA'S KIDS SAFE?
>> LET ME SAY THIS IS THE FIRST
TIME WE'VE BEEN HERE, AND OUR
HEARTS AND PRAYERS ARE WITH THE
FAMILIES, WITH THIS COMMUNITY,
SUCH A TRAGIC EVENT THAT
HAPPENED, IT SHOULD NEVER HAPPEN
TO ANY OF OUR CHILDREN OR OUR
CITIZENS, BUT THE QUESTION YOU
ASKED, HAVE WE DONE ENOUGH?
THERE IS NOTHING -- YOU CAN'T DO
EVERYTHING IT WOULD TAKE TO KEEP
EVERYBODY SAFE, BUT WE NEED TO
TRY TO DO MORE.
LOOK, WE'RE HEARING ABOUT THE
CHALLENGES THAT THIS -- THIS
YOUNG MAN HAD, THE STORIES THAT
HIS MOTHER WAS TELLING FRIENDS.
THERE ARE WARNING SIGNS LEFT AND
RIGHT ABOUT THIS YOUNG MAN, AND
WE NEED TO HAVE OUR COMMUNITIES
IN A POSITION WHERE THEY CAN
RECOGNIZE THOSE WARNING SIGNS
AND ACT ON THOSE WARNING SIGNS.
>> THE PRESIDENT HIMSELF SEEMED
TO ADDRESS YOUR STATEMENT RIGHT
THERE.
HE SAID HELPLESSNESS ISN'T A
REASON NOT TO TRY TO DO
SOMETHING.
SO ON THE SUBJECT OF MENTAL
HEALTH, SUCH A BIG CONCERN OF
YOURS, CONGRESSMAN MACK WHAT IS
THE GOVERNMENT ROLE WHEN IT
COMES TO MENTAL HEALTH?
IS THERE A ROLE?
>> FOR ME, I HAVE BEEN FOCUSED A
LOT ON THE PRESCRIPTION DRUG
EPIDEMIC AND MOVING TO THE
MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES, I
SUPPORTED THE WELL STONE MENTAL
HEALTH PARODY ACT.
MENTAL HEALTH IS PART OF
PHYSICAL HEALTH AND TREAT IT AS
SUCH.
IT ISN'T JUST A GOVERNMENT ROLE.
A FAMILY ROLE, A SOCIETAL ROLE,
A CULTURAL ROLE, IT'S EVERYWH  E
EVERYWHERE, IN OUR HOMES.
EVERY PERSON IN AMERICA HAS TO
ASK THE QUESTION, WE CAN'T JUST
LOOK TO THE GOVERNMENT FOR THE
ANSWER, ALTHOUGH THERE WILL BE
SOME ANSWERS THERE.
JUST THIS MORNING ON THE DRIVE
OVER HERE, I RESEARCHED THAT THE
CENTER OF DISEASE CONTROL HAS AN
AGENCY OR PROGRAM LOOK INTO
THESE TYPES OF VIOLENCE.
I HAD NEVER HEARD OF THAT BEFORE
UNTIL NOW, SO I WOULD LIKE KNOW
IS IT FUNDED AT THE LEVEL IT
SHOULD BE FUNDED, IS IT DOING
WHAT IT SHOULD BE DOING?
WHO IS IT REPORTING TO?
>> ONE OF THE GREATEST SOURCES
OF FUNDING FOR MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES COMES FROM MEDICAID, OF
COURSE.
I DON'T WANT TO MAKE THIS A
PARTISAN ISSUE, IT'S NOT A
PARTISAN ISSUE, BUT THE RYAN
BUDGET, FOR INSTANCE, INCLUDED
VERY BIG CUTS IN SOME INSTANCES
FOR MEDICAID.
WOULD MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES BE
AFFECTED BY THE KIND OF CUTS
THAT HAVE BEEN DISCUSSED OVER
THE PAST COUPLE OF YEARS.
>> WITH ALL DUE RESPECT, I DON'T
KNOW THAT QUESTION REALLY GETS
TO THE HEART OF THIS.
YOU SEE MEMBERS OF CONGRESS
UNDERSTAND THAT THERE IS A LOT
THAT'S UNKNOWN ABOUT MENTAL
HEALTH.
MENTAL HEALTH THERE, IS A STIGMA
IN OUR SOCIETY ABOUT MEANTALITY
HEALTH, WHICH THERE SHOULDN'T
BE.
THIS IS AN ISSUE THAT IS
OBVIOUSLY IMPORTANT TO THE
SAFETY OF OUR COMMUNITIES, AND
SO MAKING SURE THAT THERE IS
FUNDING AVAILABLE AND THAT WE
UNDERSTAND WHAT WE'RE -- WHEN WE
SAY MENTAL HEALTH, PEOPLE DON'T
EVEN REALLY UNDERSTAND WHAT THAT
IS.
BUT WHEN WE HAVE YOUNG MEN IN
OUR COMMUNITIES LIKE THE -- THE
YOUNG MAN THAT COMMITTED THIS
TRAGEDY, THESE MURDERS, THERE
WERE WARNING SIGNS EVERYWHERE,
AND WE NEED TO HAVE A SOCIETY
THAT IS LOOKING FOR THOSE
WARNING SIGNS AND KNOW HOW TO
ACT.
RIGHT NOW, NO ONE WOULD KNOW HOW
TO ACT ON THOSE ISSUES.
THAT'S WHAT WE NEED TO DO.
>> SENATOR JOE LIBERMAN, HIS
LAST FEW WEEKS AS SENATOR, HAS
SUGGESTED DOING A NATIONAL
COMMISSION OF SOME KIND TO LOOK
INTO ALL OF THESE ISSUES, I
THINK.
THE MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES, GUN
CONTROL.
WOULD THIS BE A GOOD IDEA?
WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE TO SEE COME
THAT?
>> I THINK IT'S A GREAT IDEA.
I THINK WE SHOULD HAVE A
NATIONAL DIALOG, PUT EVERYTHING
ON THE TABLE.
EVERY PARENT OR GRANDPARENT
SHOULD EXPECT THAT.
EVERYTHING SHOULD BE ON THE
TABLE AND HAVE A REASONED
DEBATE.
BACK TO THE QUESTION ABOUT THE
RYAN BUDGET, THE REASON IT'S
IMPORTANT TO SAY THIS, ALTHOUGH
I SUPPORT THE RYAN BUDGET, IT'S
SO HARD TO ALWAYS PUT THESE
THINGS IN THE TERMS OF BUDGETS.
THE COUNTRY IS FACED WITH CUTS,
BUT I SUPPORT INCREASING
MEDICAID AND SUPPORTED S CHIP
AND INCREASED MEDICAID FUNDING
ON THE STATE LEVEL.
WE LOOK AT POLITICAL ANSWERS, WE
SHOULDN'T JUMP ON SOMETHING AND
OVERSIMPLIFY IT.
PARENTS DESERVE BETTER.
THE VICTIMS OF THIS HEINOUS
TRAGEDY DESERVE BETTER, AND I
THINK WE AS A COUNTRY NEED TO
QUIT SHOUTING AT EACH OTHER AND
TRY TO FIND THE INSTANT PROBLEMS
AND EXPLOIT THEM.
EVERYTHING SHOULD BE ON THE
TABLE.
SENATOR LIBERMAN IS RIGHT.
>> THE MACKS, THANK YOU, BOTH,
SO MUCH.
I KNOW YOU JUST DID ARRIVE HERE.
SO MOVING TO BE HERE IN THIS
TOWN WHERE THE TRAGEDY DID
HAPPEN.
AND AS YOU SAID, SOMETIMES WORDS
LIKE BUDGETS AND FUNDING, THIS
AND THAT, COLD WORDS DEALING
WITH THE TRAGEDY.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
I REALLY DO APPRECIATE IT.
>>> OF COURSE, AS WE MENTIONED,
PRESIDENT OBAMA DID PLAY THE
ROLE AS COMFORTER IN CHIEF IN
NEWTOWN, TELLING PEOPLE IN THIS
COMMUNITY, THEY ARE NOT ALONE
AND THEY ARE NOT ALONE.
MORE FROM LAST NIGHT'S VIGIL,
COMING UP.
LIE HERE FOREVER.
I WISH THIS TEST DRIVE WAS OVER,
SO WE COULD HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
TEST DRIVE!
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A JETTA.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN,
$0 DUE AT SIGNING, $0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
OF THE NEWTOWN SCHOOL SHOOT
WILLING BE LAID TO REST TODAY.
>> WE GATHER HERE IN MEMORY OF
20 BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN AND 6
REMARKABLE ADULTS.
THEY LOST THEIR LIVES IN A
SCHOOL THAT COULD HAVE BEEN ANY
SCHOOL.
IN A QUIET TOWN FULL OF GOOD AND
DECENT PEOPLE.
THAT COULD BE ANY TOWN IN
AMERICA.
DANIEL, OLIVIA, JOSEPHINE, ANA,
DYLAN, MADELINE, CATHERINE,
CHASE, JESSE.
JAMES, GRACE, EMILIE, JACK,
NOAH, CAROLINE, JESSICA,
BENJAMIN, AVIELLE, ADDISON.
GOD HAS CALLED THEM ALL HOME.
FOR THOSE OF US WHO REMAIN, LET
US FIND THE STRENGTH TO CARRY ON
AND MAKE OUR COUNTRY WORTHY OF
THEIR MEMORY.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
WITH TWO TIMES THE POINTS
ON DINING IN RESTAURANTS,?
YOU MAY FIND
YOURSELF ASKING
WHY NOT, A LOT.
CHASE SAPPHIRE PREFERRED.
THERE'S MORE TO ENJOY.
WITH ODOR FREE ASPERCREME.