A QUIET, UNYIELDING ANGER.
THESE ACTS OF MASS MURDER WERE
INTENDED TO FRIGHTEN OUR NATION
TO CHAOS AND RETREAT, BUT THEY
HAVE FAILED.
OUR COUNTRY IS STRONG.
>> THOSE WHO DIED HERE, THOSE
WHO SAVED LIVES HERE, THEY
HELPED ME BELIEVE.
WE MAY NOT BE ABLE TO STOP ALL
EVIL IN THE WORLD, BUT I KNOW
THAT HOW WE TREAT ONE ANOTHER,
THAT'S ENTIRELY UP TO US.
[ APPLAUSE ]
AND I BELIEVE THAT FOR ALL OUR
IMPERFECTIONS WE ARE FULL OF
DECENCY AND GOODNESS AND THAT
THE FORCES THAT DIVIDE US ARE
NOT AS STRONG AS THOSE THAT
UNITE US.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
WATCHING THIS SPECIAL EDITION OF
"STATE OF THE UNION."
I'M CANDY CROWLEY.
BE SURE TO STICK WITH CNN FOR
CONTINUING LIVE COVERAGE AND DON
LEMON FROM NEWTOWN AND JOIN US
AT 6:00 P.M. TONIGHT FOR THE
INTERFAITH VIGIL AND THE
PRESIDENT'S REMARKS.
>>> HELLO, EVERYONE.
I'M DON LEMON REPORTING LIVE
FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
A COMMUNITY IN MOURNING AFTER A
GUNMAN WENT ON A DEADLY RAMPAGE
AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL KILLING
26 PEOPLE, 20 OF THEM YOUNG
CHILDREN.
THROUGHOUT THE DAY ON CNN WE
WILL BRING YOU THE DETAILS OF
THE VICTIMS AND THE
INVESTIGATION.
WE SHOULD TELL YOU THE PRESIDENT
IS ON THE WAY HERE.
IT HAS BEEN A DAY OF MOURNING IN
THIS COMMUNITY WITH MEMORIAL
SERVICES.
PEOPLE ARE COMING TO THIS
COMMUNITY FROM ALL OVER THE
TRI-STATE AREA, FROM ALL OVER
CONNECTICUT, NEW JERSEY, AND NEW
YORK ALL AROUND AND PAYING THEIR
RESPECTS TO PEOPLE.
AS I DROVE HERE TODAY JUST A FEW
MOMENTS AGO IN THIS LITTLE
IDYLLIC TOWN, THE ROADS WERE ALL
BLOCKED BECAUSE THERE WERE SO
MANY PEOPLE WHO WERE TRYING TO
GET IN HERE JUST TO PAY THEIR
RESPECTS TO THE PEOPLE WHO LOST
THEIR LIVES AND THEIR FAMILY AND
THEIR LOVED ONES.
WE HAVE SOME OTHER BIG STORIES
THAT ARE BREAKING TODAY AND I
WANT TO GET TO ATLANTA AND OUR
DEBORAH FEYERICK COVERING THEM
FROM THERE.
HELLO.
>> HI THERE.
WE WILL HAVE A LOT MORE COMING
UP.
WE'RE GOING TO RETURN TO YOU IN
NEWTOWN, DON.
>> ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> FIRST, A MASS SHOOTING THAT
HAS SHOCKED AND SADDENED AN
ENTIRE NATION.
MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS ARE BEING
SET UP AND VIGILS ARE BEING HELD
ALL WEEKEND FOR THE VICTIMS.
IT IS AN OVERWHELMING OUTPOURING
OF GRIEF AND SADNESS HERE FOR
THE FAMILIES WHO HAVE LOST LOVED
ONES IN FRIDAY'S MASSACRE.
♪ I ONCE WAS LOST BUT NOW
>> 150 PEOPLE ATTENDED A
CANDLELIGHT VIGIL IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, LAST NIGHT.
MANY SOBBING AS THE NAMES OF THE
VICTIMS WERE ALL READ ALLOWED.
-- ALOUD.
PRESIDENT BARACK OBAMA WILL TRY
TO COMFORT THE VICTIMS' FAMILIES
TODAY WHEN HE ARRIVES HERE,
SCHEDULED TO ARRIVE IN NEWTOWN
IN A FEW HOURS.
HE'S GOING TO MEET WITH FAMILIES
AND FIRST RESPONDERS AND THEN
TONIGHT HE WILL SPEAK AT AN
INTERFAITH VIGIL AND WE WILL
BRING THAT SERVICE TO YOU LIVE
IN ITS ENTIRETY, IN OUR 7:00
P.M. EASTERN HOUR.
THE PRESIDENT WILL BE SPEAKING
LIVE HERE.
WE HAVE TO GET TO THE
INVESTIGATION NOW.
IMPORTANT TO TELL YOU WHAT WE
KNOW.
POLICE SAY THEY ARE CONFIDENT
EVERY QUESTION INVOLVING THE
CRIME WILL BE ANSWERED.
WE'RE FINDING OUT MORE DETAILS
OF HOW THE ALLEGED GUNMAN GOT
INTO THE SCHOOL.
I WANT TO GO TO ALISON KOSIK WHO
JOINS ME WITH MORE ON THAT
INFORMATION.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW, ALISON?
>> I'M STANDING IN THE
NEIGHBORHOOD WHERE ADAM LANZA,
THE GUNMAN IN THIS MASSACRE,
USED TO LIVE WITH HIS MOM NANCY.
WE HAVEN'T CONFIRMED YET WHETHER
OR NOT THIS CRIME SCENE HAS BEEN
SHUT DOWN.
WE HAVEN'T SEEN ANY ACTIVITY
SINCE YESTERDAY AFTERNOON.
THE FOCUS, THOUGH, STILL SEEMS
TO BE ON THE SCHOOL.
WE ARE LEARNING NEW DETAILS FROM
THE GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT DAN
MALOY.
HE WAS ON "STATE OF THE UNION"
QUIT CANDY CROWLEY THIS MORNING
AND WE'RE GETTING A BETTER
PICTURE, A MORE DEVASTATING
PICTURE, OF HOW THIS GUNMAN MADE
HIS WAY INTO THE SCHOOL, WHICH
BY THE WAY HAD SECURITY.
YOU HAD TO BE BUZZED INTO THE
SCHOOL.
THERE WERE SECURITY CAMERAS
THERE AS WELL.
YOU HAD TO BE BUZZED INTO THE
SCHOOL AS OF 9:30 IN THE
MORNING.
GOVERNOR MALOY DID CONFIRM WHAT
OUR SOURCES HAVE BEEN TELLING
US, THAT THIS GUNMAN LITERALLY
BLASTED HIS WAY INTO THE SCHOOL.
HERE'S HOW THE GOVERNOR PUTS IT.
>> WHAT WE KNOW IS HE SHOT HIS
WAY INTO THE BUILDING.
HE WASN'T BUZZED IN.
HE SHOT HIS WAY IN BY SHOOTING
AN ENTRANCE INTO THE BUILDING.
THAT'S WHAT AN ASSAULT WEAPON
CAN DO FOR YOU.
YOU KNOW, WE ARE UNFORTUNATELY A
VIOLENT SOCIETY.
>> AND IT'S REALLY SCARY TO HEAR
THIS, DON, IF YOU ASK ME.
YOU THINK ABOUT HOW HE DID STORM
HIS WAY INTO THIS SCHOOL.
A LOT OF SCHOOLS HAVE THIS KIND
OF SECURITY AND NOW IT LEAVES
LOTS OF QUESTIONS, HOW SECURE
REALLY IS THAT SECURITY SYSTEM,
DON?
>> YEAH.
AND ALISON, WE'VE ALSO LEARNED
SOME NEW INFORMATION ABOUT THE
VICTIM'S DEATHS.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW ABOUT THAT?
>> AND THIS IS REALLY HARD T
HEAR.
YOU KNOW, I MEANS THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER YESTERDAY COMING OUT
AND SAYING ALL OF THE VICTIMS
WERE SHOT -- WERE SHOT MULTIPLE
TIMES, SOME SHOT ANYWHERE FROM
THREE TO 11 TIMES EACH.
THIS IS REALLY HARD STUFF TO
HEAR.
ALL OF THE CHILDREN WERE 6 OR 7
YEARS OLD, IN FIRST GRADE.
ONE THING WE ARE LEARNING FROM
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE WHO HAD A
NEWS CONFERENCE A SHORT TIME
AGO, THE PROCESS OF RELEASING
THE BODIES TO THE FAMILIES HAS
BEGUN.
AS FAR AS THE INVESTIGATION
GOES, ACCORDING TO VANCE, FOUR
WEAPONS WERE FOUND AT THE
SCHOOL, THREE WERE FOUND AT THE
HOUSE IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD WHERE
I AM, WHERE THE GUNMAN LIVED
WITH HIS MOTHER.
ALSO WE ARE LEARNING THAT THE
ATF IS FINISHED WITH TRACING THE
WEAPONS AND WHO OWNED THESE
WEAPONS.
NOW IT LOOKS LIKE FEDERAL AGENTS
ARE CHASING OTHER LEADS.
THEY'RE GOING TO 30 GUN RANGES,
400 GUN DEALERS AND FOUR
COUNTIES SURROUNDING THIS AREA
BECAUSE WHAT THEY'RE TRYING TO
FIGURE OUT, DON, WHAT THIS
GUNMANs WAS DOING BEFORE THIS
MASSACRE HAPPENED ON FRIDAY.
DON?
>> SUCH HORRIFIC DETAILS.
THANK YOU.
JOINING ME I WANT TO BRING IN
LILY AN BITMAN, THE FORMER
CHAIRMAN OF THE NEWTOWN BOARD OF
EDUCATION.
SHE HELPED GET HOCHSPRUNG THE
POSITION.
SHE VOLUNTEERED AT SANDY HOOK
FOR 15 YEARS.
IT'S DIFFICULT FOR YOU TO JOIN
US TODAY.
YOU KNEW SOME OF THE VICTIMS'
FAMILIES.
IT'S SO -- I'M NOT EVEN INVOLVED
IN THIS, AND IT'S HARD TO GET
WORDS OUT WITHOUT EVEN CRYING.
HOW ARE YOU GUYS DOING?
>> MY FAMILY HAS BEEN AFFECTED
DIRECTLY AND -- BUT I THINK THE
WORST PART OF THIS, ASIDE FROM
LOSING ALL OUR ANGELS AND SOME
AMAZING ADULTS IN OUR SCHOOL, IS
THAT THIS SCHOOL WAS SO CLOSE
AND WE HAD SUCH AN AMAZING SET
OF STAFF AND STUDENTS AND PARENT
VOLUNTEERS AND SO WHEN YOU HAVE
SOMETHING LIKE THIS HAPPEN IN AN
ENVIRONMENT WHERE THERE WAS SO
MUCH LOVE AND JOY, EVERYONE JUST
FEELS VIOLATED.
I -- AS SOMEONE, I WAS ACTUALLY
INVOLVED IN THE SCHOOL FOR 17
YEARS, AND I JUST STOPPED BEING
INVOLVED LAST SPRING AND I
WORKED WITH THE CHILDREN ON A
WEEKLY BASIS ON A NEWSPAPER
PROGRAM.
ALL MY CHILDREN WENT THROUGH THE
IT'S JUST -- IT'S UNBELIEVABLE
THAT THIS COULD HAPPEN TO A
LITTLE SCHOOL THAT HAD SO MUCH
LOVE AND JOY IN IT.
>> WHY DID YOU FEEL IT WAS
IMPORTANT TO SPEAK OUT NOW?
>> BECAUSE I NEED THE COUNTRY
AND THE WORLD TO UNDERSTAND THAT
OUT OF THIS, BE WE HAVE TO BRING
GOOD.
THIS WAS AN IDYLLIC SETTING FOR
CHILDREN AND NOW CHILDREN,
YOUNG, YOUNG CHILDREN HAVE DIED.
WE KEEP SEEING THIS IN OUR
COUNTRY.
WHEN COLUMBINE HAPPENED OUR
SCHOOL PUT IN A BUZZER SYSTEM.
A FEW MONTHS AGO WAS AURORA.
THIS KEEPS HAPPENING AND I WANT
THE DEATHS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN, SOME OF THEM SIBLINGS
OF MY CHILDREN'S FRIENDS, TO
HAVE MEANING.
INITIALLY AS A COMMUNITY WE'RE
GOING TO GIVE THOSE DEATHS
MEANING THROUGH THE LOVE THAT WE
GIVE TO ALL THE VICTIMSES AND
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE ALL DOING.
MEALS HAVE BEEN SET UP.
EVERYTHING YOU CAN IMAGINE.
BUT BEYOND THAT, GOOD MUST COME
OF THIS TRAGEDY.
>> YEAH.
I HAD BEEN TRYING TO TELL PEOPLE
AND EXPLAIN TO THE AUDIENCE AND
PEOPLE ON SOCIAL MEDIA JUST HOW
DIFFICULT IT IS TO BE HERE AND
IT'S DIFFICULT FOR THE MEDIA,
BUT THIS IS OUR JOBS.
>> RIGHT.
>> BUT FOR THE PEOPLE WHO LIVE
HERE AND THE PEOPLE WHO ARE
AFFECTED BY THIS, WHEN YOU LOOK
AT THIS TOWN, IT LOOKS LIKE A
CHRISTMAS POSTCARD AND YOU THINK
ABOUT ALLS THOSE LIVES, THERE'S
NOT GOING TO BE ANY -- ANOTHER
PERSON AT CHRISTMAS.
>> RIGHT.
>> IT'S NOT GOING TO BE ANOTHER
GRADUATION.
ANY OF THOSE THINGS.
>> IT'S BIGGER THAN THAT.
THIS MEANS THAT THIS SCHOOL THAT
WAS SUCH A UNIT, ISN'T GOING TO
EXIST FOR SOME TIME.
WE'RE MOVING TO MONROE, RIGHT?
THAT'S WHERE THAT LITTLE SCHOOL
WILL BE TEMPORARILY.
IT ALSO HAS RIPPLE AFFECTS OUT.
THE KIDS IN COLLEGE RIGHT NOW
THAT WENT TO THAT SCHOOL,
THEY'RE DEVASTATED BECAUSE THEIR
MEMORIES OF THAT SCHOOL HAVE
JUST BEEN CRASHED.
IT BEGINS WITH THE DEATH OF
BABIES, AND IT RIPPLES OUT.
EVERYONE IN NEWTOWN KNOWS EACH
OTHER.
>> HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN TO THE
PEOPLE ON THE OTHER SIDE OF THAT
CAMERA, WHAT THEY CAN DO?
EVERYBODY'S ASKING ME, WHAT CAN
WE DO TO HELP?
CAN WE PRAY?
OBVIOUSLY PRAYERS WILL HELP.
BUT WHAT CAN THEY DO, PEOPLE
WATCHING NOT ONLY IN THE U.S.
BUT AROUND THE WORLD TO HELP
THIS COMMUNITY?
>> I WOULD LIKE EVERYONE TO LEAD
WITH LOVE AND NOT JUST HELP THE
TOWN BUT HELP OUR COUNTRY COME
TO TERMS WITH THESE SITUATIONS.
SENDING US LOVE AND PRAYERS,
THAT'S AN AMAZING THING.
I'M GETTING IT FROM WHERE I'M
FROM IN THE MIDWEST AND I CAN'T
SAY ENOUGH ABOUT THAT AND I KNOW
ALL MY FRIENDS ARE TOO.
BUT, WHAT IS THE MOST IMPORTANT
THING WE CAN DO IS LEAD WITH
LOVE AND THEN LOOK AT OUR
SITUATION AS A COUNTRY AND SAY,
DOES IT STOP NOW?
DO WE HAVE SOLUTIONS?
I'M NOT -- I DON'T KNOW IF IT'S
GUN CONTROL, NO MORE GLASS DOORS
IN SCHOOL BUILDINGS.
IF THOSE DOORS WEREN'T GLASS
MAYBE THIS WOULDN'T HAVE
HAPPENED.
WE AS A COUNTRY HAVE TO USE THIS
TO COME TOGETHER AND LOOK AT ALL
THE SOLUTIONS, MENTAL HEALTH,
EVERYTHING.
SO WHAT CAN THE WORLD DO?
LOVE EACH OTHER.
AND WORK TOGETHER AND NO MORE
GRIDLOCK ON ANYTHING.
FIGURE THIS OUT SO NO MORE
6-YEAR-OLDS HAVE TO DIE OR WATCH
THEIR TEACHER DIE IN THEIR
CLASSROOM, IN A PLACE THAT HAS
FOR YEARS BEEN A PLACE OF JOY
AND LOVE.
THAT'S JUST WRONG.
IT'S WRONG.
>> OKAY.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
I APPRECIATE YOU BEING HERE.
>> GOD BLESS YOU.
YOU KNOW SOME OF THE FAMILIES.
HOW ARE THEY DOING?
>> A MESS.
THEY'RE A MESS.
HOW WOULD YOU DO?
>> YEAH.
>> I MEAN, NOPE.
YEP.
>> OUR THOUGHTS AND PRAYERS.
>> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU.
>> WE NEED TO GET TO A CNN
PRODUCER.
WE'RE HEARING THERE IS SOME
ACTIVITY GOING ON AT A CHURCH
AND THE PRODUCER JOINS US NOW ON
THE PHONE.
IT'S AT SAINT ROSE OF LIMA
CATHOLIC CHURCH IN NEWTOWN.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL US?
>> I CAN TELL YOU THAT ABOUT 30,
35 MINUTES AGO, PARISHIONERS
WERE SEEN LEAVING THE CHURCH AND
NUMEROUS LAW ENFORCEMENT
VEHICLES ENTERING THE GROUNDS AT
A RAPID PACE.
I TALKED TO ONE YOUNG WOMAN WHO
WAS IN THE FOYER OF THE CHURCH
WHO TOLD EVERYONE TO LEAVE.
THEY WEREN'T TELLING PEOPLE WHY.
SHE SAID AN INDIVIDUAL IN FIRE
DEPARTMENT GEAR SAID THERE HAD
BEEN A THREAT AND PEOPLE WERE
RUSHING OUT OF THE CHURCH.
>> OKAY.
AGAIN, PARDON THAT.
TRYING TO GET THE INFORMATION TO
ME.
MY PRODUCER IS TALKING TO ME.
IT'S VIN WHO'S ON THE PHONE.
DO YOU KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT
WHAT'S GOING ON AT THE CHURCH OR
JUST SEEING PEOPLE LEAVING AND
POLICE ACTIVITY?
NO OTHER INFORMATION?
>> PEOPLE LEFT.
THERE IS NO INFORMATION AS TO
WHY THEY WERE TOLD TO LEAVE.
THERE IS HEAVY CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE ACTIVITY HERE.
PROBABLY ABOUT TEN MINUTES AGO,
A COLUMN OF STATE POLICE
OFFICERS DRESSED IN CAMOUFLAGE
GEAR, CARRYING RIFLES WITH LARGE
CLIPS, YOU KNOW, WEARING
MILITARY STYLE GEAR, WENT INTO A
BUILDING THAT WAS ACROSS THE
PARKING LOT FROM THE CHURCH
WHICH APPEARS TO BE AN
EDUCATIONAL CENTER AFFILIATED
WITH THE CHURCH.
RIGHT NOW, THOSE STATE POLICE
OFFICERS ARE FILING BACK TOWARDS
THE MAIN BUILDING OF THE CHURCH
AND THAT APPEARS TO BE ALL WE
KNOW RIGHT NOW.
>> ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
KEEP AN EYE ON THAT FOR US AND
WE'LL GET BACK TO YOU IF THERE'S
NEW INFORMATION ON THAT.
>>> THERE ARE SOME DEVELOPING
NEWS COMING OUT OF WASHINGTON
RIGHT NOW.
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER HAS
COME UP WITH A PROPOSAL, THE
PRESIDENT AND DEMOCRATS CAN
ACCEPT TO AVOID THE FISCAL
CLIFF?
HAS HE?
WE HAVE THE DETAILS ON THAT.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HAD
A SECURITY SYSTEM THAT CONDUCTED
LOCKDOWN DRILLS.
WE'LL TALK TO A SECURITY EXPERT
ABOUT WHAT ELSE COULD BE DONE TO
HELP.
[ sniffs ] I HAVE A COLD.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
Capella University understands
back from rough economic times.
Employees are being forced to do
more with less.
And the need for capable leaders
is greater than ever.
When you see these problems do
you take a step back,
or do you want to dive right in?
With a degree in business from
Capella University, you'll have
the knowledge to go further in
your career than you ever
thought possible.
Let's get started at CAPELLA.EDU
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME FOR CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
Music is a universal language.
But when I was in an accident...
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
Information on my phone.
Connection to doctors who
get where I'm from.
And tools to estimate what
my care may cost.
So I never missed a beat.
We're more than 78,000
people looking out for
more than 70
million Americans.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.
>>> WANT TO TELL YOU ABOUT THE
DEVELOPING NEWS ON CNN.
ST. ROSE OF LIMA CATHOLIC
CHURCH, THERE HAS BEEN A THREAT,
BELIEVED TO BE A THREAT THERE.
THE CHURCH WAS EVACUATED, PEOPLE
WERE LEAVING THE CHURCH.
THAT'S A PICTURE WE HAVE THERE.
THIS CHURCH IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, NOT ANY IMMEDIATE
WORD ON WHY THAT CHURCH WAS
EVACUATED.
BUT IT IS BEING REPORTED BY
OTHER MEDIA IT'S POSSIBLY A NEW
THREAT.
YOU CAN SEE THE POLICE ARE ON
THE SCENE THERE, EMERGENCY
WORKERS ON THE SCENE AND TRYING
TO FIGURE OUT WHAT'S GOING ON.
AS SOON AS WE GET MORE
INFORMATION ON THAT WE'LL BRING
IT TO YOU ON CNN.
>>> THERE'S A LOT GOING ON HERE
IN NEWTOWN, BUT WE WANT TO HEAD
BACK TO CNN HEADQUARTERS IN
ATLANTA AND GET TO DEB FEYERICK
FOR A LOOK AT OTHER NEWS MAKING
HEADLINES RIGHT NOW.
DEB?
>> THANKS, DON.
LAWMAKERS COULD BE CLOSER TO A
DEAL AVOIDING THE SO-CALLED
FISCAL CLIFF.
A SOURCE TELLS CNN HOUSE SPEAKER
JOHN BOEHNER HAS OFFERED TO
INCLUDE HIGHER TAX RATES ON
MILLIONAIRES.
THE WHITE HOUSE IS STILL HOLDING
TO ITS $250,000 THRESHOLD.
UNLESS A DEAL IS REACHED BY
JANUARY 1st, PRACTICALLY
EVERYONE WILL BE HIT WITH A TAX
INCREASE.
>>> IT APPEARS PRESIDENT OBAMA
HAS TAPPED MASSACHUSETTS SENATOR
JOHN KERRY AS HIS NEXT SECRETARY
OF STATE.
THE SOURCE SAYS THE PRESIDENT
MAY MAKE THE ANNOUNCEMENT THIS
WEEK.
KERRY NARROWLY LOST THE
PRESIDENCY IN 2004 TO PRESIDENT
GEORGE W. BUSH.
HE'S CHAIRMAN OF THE SENATE
FOREIGN RELATIONS COMMITTEE AND
A DECORATED VETERAN OF THE
VIETNAM WAR.
>>> IN CALIFORNIA A FRIGHTENING
INCIDENT FOR SHOPPERS AT A MALL
PARKING LOT IN NEWPORT BEACH.
A MAN IN THE PARKING LOT, FIRED
50 SHOTS IN THE AIR YESTERDAY.
STORES FILLED WITH HOLIDAY
SHOPPERS QUICKLY LOCKED THEIR
DOORS.
NO ONE WAS HIT.
ONE PERSON SUFFERED MINOR
INJURIES TRYING TO GET OUT OF
THE AREA.
THE SUSPECT IS IN CUSTODY.
POLICE HAVE NOT GIVEN A REASON
FOR THE SHOOTING.
>>> LET'S GO BACK TO DON LEMON
LIVE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
>> AFTER THE MASSACRE AT
COLUMBINE HIGH SCHOOL IN
LITTLETON, COLORADO, IN 1999,
SCHOOLS STARTED IMPLEMENTING
STRONGER SAFETY MEASURES.
I WANT TO BRING IN KEN.
COME IN HERE NOW.
THE PRESIDENT OF THE NATIONAL
SCHOOL SAFETY AND COMMUNITY
SERVICES, DOES TRAINING AND
CONSULTING ON SCHOOL SAFETY AND
EMERGENCY PREPAREDNESS.
AT THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY, I
WANT IT SHOW YOU THIS, TEACHERS,
STAFF, STUDENTS HAD BEEN BRIEFED
ON HOW TO HANDLE A LOCKDOWN
SITUATION.
A SECURITY SYSTEM WAS INTRODUCED
THIS YEAR FOR VISITORS TO RING A
BELL, SIGN IN AND PERHAPS
PRODUCE A PHOTO I.D.
AFTER 9:30 A.M., THE DOORS WERE
LOCKED.
WHAT, IF ANYTHING, COULD HAVE
BEEN DONE TO PREVENT THIS
TRAGEDY IF THEY HAD THAT IN
PLACE?
>> THAT TYPE OF SYSTEMs IS
FAIRLY COMMON FOR ELEMENTARY
SCHOOLS ACROSS THE COUNTRY AND
ANY TYPE OF TECHNOLOGY IS A
DETERRENT FOR THOSE WHO CAN BE
DETERRED, A DELAY FOR OTHERS
POSSIBLY BUT IT'S NOT FOOLPROOF.
WE TEND TO RELY HEAVILY ON
TECHNOLOGY.
WE'RE HEARING CALLS NOW ABOUT
METAL DETECTORS.
DO WE NEED THAT IN THE SCHOOL.
I SEE WE NEED MENTAL DETECTORS
RATHER THAN METAL DETECTORS.
METAL DETECTOR, DOESN'T GIVE
THAT GUARANTEE THAT PEOPLE WANT.
I'M A FATHER.
I HAVE TWO ELEMENTARY-AGED
CHILDREN.
I WOULD LOVE TO HAVE 100%
GUARANTEE.
THE REALITY IS AS A SAFETY
PROFESSIONAL NOBODY CAN GIVE ME
THAT.
I WANT TO SEE MY PRINCIPALS ARE
TAKING STEPS TO REDUCE THE RISK.
WE TRY TO REDUCE THE NUMBER OF
OPEN DOORS.
WE PUT THE SECURITY TECHNOLOGY
IN, TRAIN OUR STAFF, BUT -- AND
YOU PREPARE FOR TO MANAGE THINGS
AS BEST YOU CAN.
>> WHAT ABOUT LAYERS, YOU HAVE
ONE DOOR YOU WALK IN, THAT DOOR
CLOSES AND ANOTHER LOCKED DOOR.
WILL THAT HELP TO HAVE THOSE?
>> THAT'S AN EXTRA TOOL.
WE'RE SEEING THAT PARTICULARLY
IN OUR MIDDLE SCHOOLS AND HIGH
SCHOOLS NOW.
STEP INTO THE FIRST LEVEL, AND
THEN YOU GET FUNNELED INTO THE
OFFICE, BUZZED IN TO THERE
BEFORE YOU CAN GET IN THE REST
OF THE BUILDING.
ASSUMING THE PERSON GOES TO THE
FRONT DOOR.
THE PART OF THE TECHNOLOGY AND
THE DESIGN IS, THAT IT'S ONLY AS
GOOD AS A HUMAN ELEMENT BEHIND
IT.
IF YOU HAVE KIDS AND ADULTS WHO
PROP OPEN DOORS, STAFF WHO DON'T
GREET AND CHALLENGE STRANGERS
BECAUSE SOMEBODY CAN GET IN, ANY
TECHNOLOGY IS ONLY AS GOOD AS
THE WEAKEST HUMAN LINK BEHIND
IT.
>> WHAT ABOUT GLEN BITMAN WHO
WORKED FOR THE SCHOOL SYSTEM,
SAID MAYBE NO MORE GLASS DOORS
IN SCHOOLS.
IS THAT FEASIBLE?
>> WHAT YOU CAN DO CERTAINLY IS
MINIMIZE THE GLASS.
RATHER THAN HAVING A FULL GLASS
DOOR, TAKE IT DOWN TO WHERE HALF
OF THE DOOR IS GLASS SO YOU CAN
SEE THROUGH.
YOU WANT TO BE ABLE TO SEE WHO'S
ON THE OTHER SIDE BUT YOU DON'T
NEED THE WHOLE DOOR MADE OUT OF
GLASS.
>> WE HAVE TALKED ABOUT THIS
BEFORE.
REMEMBER COLUMBINE.
SECURITY BECAME A BIG PRIORITY
IN THE YEARS FOLLOWING COLUMBINE
IN 1999.
DO YOU THINK THAT A PUSH HAS
DIMINISHED IN RECENT YEARS FOR
ADDED SECURITY WITH SCHOOLS?
>> YEAH.
WE'VE DEAN A COMPETITION FOR --
WE'VE SEEN A COMPETITION FOR
TIME AND MONEY.
FEDERAL, STATE AND LOCAL
EDUCATION BUDGETS HAVE BEEN
CUTS.
SCHOOL SECURITY THE FIRST ON THE
LIST.
WE'RE ALSO IN COMPETITION FOR
TIME.
THE HOT BUTTON ISSUES IN
EDUCATION TODAY ARE TEST
SCHOOLS, IMPROVING ACADEMICS AND
EDUCATION REFORM AND HAS PUSHED
SCHOOL SAFETY TO THE BACK
BURNER.
THERE ARE MANY THINGS IN
EDUCATION, BUT PARENTS WILL
FORGIVE YOU IF YOUR TEST SCORES
GO DOWN, BUT LESS FORGIVING IF
SOMETHING HAPPENS TO THE KIDS.
>> LOOK AT SHOOTINGS ON COLLEGE
CAMPUSES OR SCHOOLS, THERE ARE
MANY DISGRUNTLED STUDENTS.
IS YOUR GREATEST CONCERN THE
THREAT AS YOU SAID OF MENTAL
HEALTH WHEN IT COMES TO
SCHOOL-AGED CHILDREN?
>> TAKE A LOOK AT WHAT'S GOING
ON IN OUR SOCIETY.
ECONOMIC PRESSURE, STRESSORS ON
FAMILIES THAT ARE INTENSE NOW
MORE THAN EVER AND A LOT OF
UNDIAGNOSED AND UNTREATED MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES FLOATING AROUND
OUR STREETS.
THE CHALLENGE FOR EDUCATOREDUCA
IT'S STUDENT ORIENTED WE HAVE
ACCESS TO THOSE KIDS AND MAY GET
RED FLAGS.
IF IT'S A CHANGER -- STRANGER
OFF THE STREET HOW CAN A
PRINCIPAL PREPARE?
>> I HATE TO SAY THIS CLICHE.
IF THIS ISN'T WHEN YOU HAVE THE
YOUNG PRECIOUS CHILDREN BEING
KILLED, IF WE DON'T DO SOMETHING
NOW WHEN WILL WE DO SOMETHING.
>> THE QUESTION ISN'T WHETHER
IT'S A WAKE-UP CALL, WILL WE HIT
THE SNOOZE BUTTON AND GO BACK TO
SLEEP.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT THIS IN
SCHOOLS ACROSS THE COUNTRY IN
UPCOMING WEEKS, SIX MONTHS OR
SIX YEARS FROM NOW, WITHOUT AN
INCIDENT WILL WE STILL HAVE THE
SAME CONVERSATION AND THE
HISTORY TELLS US WE TYPICALLY
DON'T.
>> THANK YOU.
I APPRECIATE IT.
WISH WE WOULD SEE EACH OTHER
UNDER BETTER CIRCUMSTANCES.
>> MOST PEOPLE TOUCHED BY THIS
TRAGEDY WANT TO GRIEVE AND THEY
WANT TO DO IT IN PRIVATE.
ONE FATHER HAS SPOKEN OUT
PUBLICLY ABOUT THE DEATH OF HIS
SMALL DAUGHTER AND HIS WORDS ARE
PROVING TO BE AN INSPIRATION TO
ALL OF US.
♪ OOH BABY, LOOKS LIKE
YOU NEED A LITTLE HELP THERE ♪
♪ OOH BABY,
CAN I DO FOR YOU TODAY? ♪
[ Female Announcer ] NEED HELP
KEEPING YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE?
ALIGN CAN HELP.
ONLY ALIGN HAS BIFANTIS,
A PATENTED PROBIOTIC
THAT NATURALLY HELPS MAINTAIN
YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE.
TRY ALIGN TO HELP RETAIN
A BALANCED DIGESTIVE SYSTEM.
TRY THE #1 GASTROENTEROLOGIST
RECOMMENDED PROBIOTIC.
ALIGN.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
LOOK THIS ISN'T
MY FIRST CHRISTMAS.
THESE DEALS ALL SEEM GREAT
AT THE TIME...
BUT LATER...
[ shirt ]
MERRY CHRISTMAS, EVERYBODY!
NOT SO MUCH.
HO HO HO!
THIS ISN'T
THAT KIND OF DEAL.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SAVE ON GROUND SHIPPING
AT FEDEX OFFICE.
>>> ON FRIDAY, LIVES FOR MANY
FAMILIES IN NEWTOWN CHANGED
FOREVER.
IT IS UNIMAGINABLE PARENTS SENT
THEIR CHILDREN OFF TO SCHOOL AND
THEN IN A MATTER OF A FEW SHORT
HOURS THEY FACED A HORROR OF
NEVER SEEING THEM AGAIN.
BUT AS CNN SHOWS US, ONE FATHER
IS SPEAKING OUT ABOUT HOW HE AND
HIS FAMILY WILL FIND PEACE.
>> I DON'T KNOW HOW TO GET
THROUGH SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
MY WIFE AND I DON'T UNDERSTAND
HOW TO PROCESS ALL OF THIS.
>> Reporter: HOW CAN YOU, ASKED
ROBBIE PARKER, WHEN YOU LOSE
YOUR 6-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER,
EMILIE, HIS BRIGHT LIGHT?
ARTIST WITH CRAYONS, ELDER
SISTER TO A 3 AND 4-YEAR-OLD.
>> SHE WAS THE TYPE OF PERSON
THAT COULD JUST LIGHT UP A ROOM.
SHE -- SHE ALWAYS HAD SOMETHING
KIND TO SAY ABOUT ANYBODY.
HER LOVE AND THE STRENGTH THAT
SHE GAVE US AND THE EXAMPLE THAT
SHE SHOWED US IS REMARKABLE.
SHE IS AN INCREDIBLE PERSON.
AND I'M SO BLESSED TO BE HER
DAD.
>> WE'RE JUST DEVASTATED THAT
SOMEONE SO BEAUTIFUL AND
PERFECT, IS NO LONGER GOING TO
BE IN OUR LIVES AND FOR NO
REASON.
>> Reporter: BUT THEN, JUST A
DAY AFTER LOSING THIS LITTLE
GIRL TO VIOLENCE, HER
30-YEAR-OLD FATHER SAID VERY
SIMPLY, I AM NOT ANGRY.
>> AS WE MOVE ON FROM WHAT
HAPPENED HERE, WHAT HAPPENED TO
SO MANY PEOPLE, LET IT NOT TURN
INTO SOMETHING THAT DEFINES US.
BUT SOMETHING THAT INSPIRES US
TO BE BETTER, TO BE MORE
COMPASSIONATE, AND MORE HUMBLE
PEOPLE.
BEST THING THAT I CAN THINK OF
TO DO TO MOVE ON IS TO HELP
OTHER PEOPLE.
WHEN YOU HELP OTHER PEOPLE, YOU
FEEL BETTER ABOUT YOURSELF.
AND THE MORE PEOPLE THAT HELP
OTHER PEOPLE, THE MORE PEOPLE
ARE BLESSED.
>> Reporter: THE FAMILY MOVED TO
NEWTOWN FROM SALT LAKE JUST
EIGHT MONTHS AGO BECAUSE
EMILIE'S FATHER GOT A JOB AT THE
LOCAL HOSPITAL WHERE HE CARES
FOR NEWBORNS.
BRETT KELLER IS THE FAMILY'S
BISHOP.
>> I REALLY DON'T KNOW HOW THEY
ARE COPING AND DEALING AS WELL
AS THEY ARE.
THEY ARE JUST TRULY STRONG,
FAITHFUL, AND BELIEVING PEOPLE
AND I THINK THEY'RE FOCUSED ON
FAMILY AND THE IMPORTANCE OF
FAMILY IN THEIR LIFE IS REALLY
WHAT IS SUSTAINING THEM AND
HELPING THEM RIGHT NOW.
>> YOU CAN NEVER STOP BEING THE
BEST PARENT THAT YOU CAN BE.
YOU CAN ALWAYS BE BETTER.
YOU CAN ALWAYS BE MORE PATIENT,
MORE LOVING AND UNDERSTANDING
AND WILLING TO ACCEPT YOUR
CHILDREN FOR WHO THEY ARE.
I REALLY HOPE THAT AS I CONTINUE
TO BE A DAD TO MY TWO CHILDREN,
THAT I CAN -- IF ANYBODY LOOKS
BACK ON MY LIFE THE NUMBER ONE
THING THEY CAN SAY ABOUT ME IS I
WAS A GREAT DAY.
>> Reporter: CNN, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> FOR MORE INFORMATION ON HOW
YOU CAN HELP THOSE AFFECTED BY
THE SHOOTING, GO TO
CNN.COM/IMPACT.
WE WANT TO UPDATE THE DEVELOPING
NEWS WE TOLD YOU ABOUT A MOMENT
AGO.
THE ST. ROSE OF LIMA KAT LISH
CHURCH EVACUATED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
POLICE INVESTIGATED A THREAT AND
SAID THEY HAVE FOUND NOTHING.
IT IS ALL CLEAR.
IF MORE INFORMATION COMES WE'LL
BRING IT TO YOU.
THERE ARE THE PICTURES OF POLICE
EVACUATING THAT CHURCH HERE.
THEY INVESTIGATED A THREAT,
FOUND NOTHING, IT'S ALL CLEAR
NOW.
>>> MOVING ON, SHARING THEIR
STORIES OF LOSS AS A WAY OF
HEALING.
SOME FAMILIES LIKE THE ONE WE
JUST MET FIND THAT TALKING ABOUT
THEIR LOSS AND LOST LOVED ONES
THEY FIND IT HELPS.
WE'LL MEET ANOTHER ONE OF THOSE
FAMILIES.
STAY WITH US.
CAN I HELP YOU?
I HEARD YOU GUYS CAN SHIP GROUND
FOR LESS THAN THE UPS STORE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I'VE LEARNED THE ONLY WAY TO GET
A HOLIDAY DEAL IS TO CAMP OUT.
YOU KNOW WE'VE BEEN OPEN
ALL NIGHT.
IS THIS A TRICK
TO GET MY SPOT?
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SAVE ON GROUND SHIPPING
AT FEDEX OFFICE.
That was ME...
the day I learned I had
to start insulin
for my type 2 diabetes.
ME...
thinking my only option was the
vial and syringe dad used.
And ME...
discovering once-daily
Levemir® FlexPen.
FlexPen® is prefilled.
Doesn't need
refrigeration
for up to
42 days.
No drawing from a vial.
Dial the exact dose.
Inject by pushing a button.
FlexPen® is insulin delivery...
MY way.
Levemir® (insulin detemir
[rDNA origin] injection)
is a long-acting insulin
used to control high blood sugar
in adults and children
with diabetes and is not
recommended to treat
diabetic ketoacidosis.
Do not use Levemir® if
you are allergic
to any of its ingredients.
The most common side effect
is low blood sugar,
which may cause
symptoms such as sweating,
shakiness, confusion,
and headache.
Severe low blood sugar can be
serious and life threatening.
Ask your healthcare provider
about alcohol use,
operating machinery, or driving.
Other possible side
effects include
injection site reactions.
Tell your healthcare provider
about all medicines you take
and all of your
medical conditions.
Get medical help right away
if you experience
serious allergic
reactions, such as body rash,
trouble with breathing, fast
heartbeat, or sweating.
With FlexPen®... say good night
to vial and syringe.
Ask your doctor about
Levemir® FlexPen.
Covered by
90% of insurance plans,
including Medicare.
Find your co-pay at
MyFlexPen.com.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN DIARRHEA HITS,
KAOPECTATE STOPS IT FAST.
POWERFUL LIQUID RELIEF
SPEEDS TO THE SOURCE.
FAST.
[ Male Announcer ]
STOP THE UH-OH FAST
WITH KAOPECTATE.
>>> AND JUST ABOUT TWO HOURS,
PRESIDENT BARACK OBAMA HEADS
HERE TO NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
HE'S GOING TO MEET WITH THE
FAMILIES OF THE 26 VICTIMS
KILLED IN FRIDAY'S MASS SHOOTING
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE PRESIDENT WILL ALSO SPEAK AT
AN INTERFAITH VIGIL TONIGHT.
WE'RE GOING TO BRING THAT
SERVICE TO YOU LIVE HERE ON CNN
AT 7:00 P.M. EASTERN.
THE PRESIDENT WILL SPEAK HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT AND WE'LL
BRING IT TO YOU ON CNN.
WE'RE FOLLOWING THE LATEST
DEVELOPMENTS ON THE SHOOTING
INVESTIGATION FOR YOU AND HERE'S
WHAT WE KNOW RIGHT NOW.
CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR DAN MALOY
SAYS A SUSPECT, A 20-YEAR-OLD
SUSPECT, SHOT HIS WAY INTO THE
SCHOOL.
WE'VE ALSO LEARNED ALL 20 OF THE
CHILDREN KILLED INSIDE THE
SCHOOL WERE SHOT MULTIPLE TIMES
AND ALL OF THEM WERE 6 AND 7
YEARS OLD.
INVESTIGATORS ARE STILL
PROCESSING THAT CRIME SCENE AND
POLICE SAY THEY EXPECT ALL
QUESTIONS SURROUNDING THE CAUSE
IN THIS CASE WILL EVENTUALLY BE
ANSWERED.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER'S OFFICE
STARTING TO RELEASE THE BODIES
OF THE 26 VICTIMS BA TO THEIR
FAMILIES NOW.
FUNERALS ARE EXPECTED TO BE HELD
THIS WEEK.
>>> WE ARE LEARNING MORE ABOUT
THE LIVES OF THE SHOOTING
MASSACRE VICTIMS AN CNN'S NICK
VALENCIA IS BACK IN THE NEWSROOM
IN ATLANTA WITH MORE ON THAT.
WE HEARD FROM ONE CHILD'S FAMILY
LAST NIGHT AND I UNDERSTAND YOU
HAVE BEEN IN TOUCH WITH ANOTHER
FAMILY?
>> YEAH.
GOOD AFTERNOON, DON.
SOME OF THE FAMILIES THAT WERE
VICTIMS OF THE NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, SHOOTING, SO FAR
HAVE BEEN MORE PRIVATE ABOUT
THEIR LOSS, BUT SOME, THEY
REALLY WANT YOU TO KNOW ABOUT
THE PEOPLE AND LOVED ONES THEY
LOST.
OLIVA ENGEL'S FAMILY I ONE.
THIS IS A DEVASTATING TIME.
JUST A FEW WEEKS AGO THEY TOOK
THESE CHRISTMAS PHOTOS FOR THE
HOLIDAY SEASON.
THEY'VE SINCE POSTED THOSE
PHOTOS ON 6-YEAR-OLD FAMILY
TRIBUTE PAGE ON FACEBOOK AND THE
FAMILY SAID OLIVA'S PHYSICAL
LOSS WILL BE FELT EVERY DAY BY
THOSE WHO LOVED HER MOST.
HER SPARKLY SPIRIT WILL LIVE ON.
SHE LOVED SCHOOL, ESPECIALLY
MATH AND READING, AND EVEN
OUTSIDE THE CLASSROOM SHE WAS
VERY ACTIVE, INVOLVED IN A LOT
OF ACTIVITIES RANGING FROM
BALLET TO TENNIS.
EVEN DAISY GIRL SCOUTS.
HER FAVORITE COLORS WERE PINK
AND PURPLE AND EACH EVENING SHE
LED GRACE AT THE DINNER TABLE
FOR HER FAMILY.
HER FAMILY SAYS SHE WAS SMART,
BUBBLY AND UNBELIEVABLING
ENTERTAINING.
IN A MUSIC RECITAL SHE WAS
SUPPOSED TO PLAY AN ANGEL AND
YESTERDAY POIGNANTLY A LOCAL
PASTOR IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
SAID TODAY HEAVEN HAS ONE MORE
ANGEL.
DON?
>> MY GOD.
SUCH BEAUTIFUL FAMILY, SUCH
BEAUTIFUL PICTURES.
I JUST -- I CAN'T EVEN IMAGINE.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> DEB FEYERICK IS BACK IN
ATLANTA AND HAS OTHER FAMILIES.
>> DON, A DEAL COULD FINALLY BE
IN THE WORKS TO AVOID THE
SO-CALLED FISCAL CLIFF.
A SOURCE TELLS CNN HOUSE SPEAKER
THAT JOHN BOEHNER HAS OFFERED TO
INCLUDE HIGHER TAX RATES ON
MILLIONAIRES.
THE WHITE HOUSE IS STILL HOLDING
TO ITS $250,000 THRESHOLD UNLESS
A DEAL IS REACHED BY JANUARY
1st, PRACTICALLY EVERYONE WILL
BE HIT WITH A TAX INCREASE.
>>> EGYPT'S MUSLIM BROTHERHOOD
DECLARED A NARROW VICTORY IN THE
FIRST ROUND OF HOTLY CONTESTED
CONSTITUTIONAL REFERENDUM.
THIS IS ONLY THE FIRST WEEKEND
OF VOTING.
THE REST OF THE COUNTRY WILL
VOTE NEXT WEEKEND.
ELECTION MONITORS REPORT SOME
CLAIMS OF VOTER INTIMIDATION AND
EARLY POLL CLOSINGS.
>>> AND FORMER SOUTH AFRICAN
PRESIDENT NELSON MANDELA IS
RECOVERING IN A HOSPITAL IN PE
TORE YA.
THE 94-YEAR-OLD HAD GALLSTONES
REMOVED YESTERDAY.
ACCORDING TO A STATEMENT FROM
THE PRESIDENT ZUMA'S OFFICE.
HE WAS HOSPITALIZED LAST WEEKEND
FOR A LUNG INFECTION.
HE'S BEEN KEEPING A LOW PROFILE
FOR YEARS.
>>> WE'RE GOING TO TAKE YOU BACK
TO NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, FOR THE
LATEST THERE WITH DON LEMON.
DON?
>> AND DEB, BE I KNOW YOU'RE A
MOM AND YOU SAW THE PICTURES
THERE OF LITTLE OLIVA AND ALL
THE PICTURES WE HAVE BEEN
SEEING, I HATED TO BE SO ABRUPT
WITH THROWING BACK TO YOU, BUT
WHAT CAN YOU SAY?
IT'S JUST --
>> I WAS LOOKING AT THAT CHILD
AT 6 YEARS OLD, AND I THINK OF
MY DAUGHTER AT 6 YEARS OLD AND
THEY HAVE THIS INCREDIBLY FULL
AND RICH LIFE AND YOU SAY, MY
CHILD IS 6, MY CHILD IS 6 AND
THIS LITTLE HUMAN BEING AND THEN
THEY TURN 7 AND THAT 6-YEAR-OLD
IS ALMOST A MEMORY AND THEN YOU
HAVE THIS BEAUTIFUL LITTLE
7-YEAR-OLD AND THEN A BEAUTIFUL
8-YEAR-OLD AND IT'S LIKE YOU
CAN'T EVEN IMAGINE THE YEARS
THAT THEY GROW INTO AND THEY
DEVELOPED AND THE RICHNESS THAT
THEY BRING, EVERY SINGLE DAY TO
YOUR LIFE AS THEY GET OLDER, AS
THEY MATURE, AS THEIR SENSE OF
HUMOR GETS KENNER AND THEIR
INTELLIGENCE, THEIR INTELLECT
GETS SHARPER.
YOU KNOW, I THINK OF MY OWN KIDS
JUST RUNNING AROUND THE CORNER
JUMPING ON ME WHENEVER I WALK
THROUGH THE DOOR.
AND I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHAT IT
WOULD BE LIKE NOT TO HAVE THAT.
>> AS JOURNALISTS, I HAVE NEVER
BEEN AT A LOSS FOR WORDS AND ON
THIS STORY I'M TRULY AT A LOSS
FOR WORDS.
I WOKE UP IN THE MIDDLE OF THE
NIGHT THINKING, I HOPE I'M
DREAMING BUT SADLY I WAS IN
ANOTHER HOTEL ROOM IN ANOTHER
CITY COVERING ANOTHER TRAGEDY
WITH A GUN AND YOUNG PEOPLE.
>> YEAH.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> TRAGEDY HERE IN CONNECTICUT
IS TOUGH FOR THE ENTIRE
COMMUNITY AND THOSE NOT DIRECTLY
AFFECTED STILL WANT TO MAKE A
DIFFERENCE.
WE'LL HEAR FROM THEM.
[ sniffs ] I HAVE A COLD.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
TO COME HOME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE...
SADLY, THEIR BROTHER'S
WHITE CHRISTMAS
JUST GOT "BLACKED OUT."
[ Brother ]
BUT IT'S THE FAMILY PARTY!
REALLY JINGLES YOUR BELLS,
DOESN'T IT?
MY GIFT TO YOU!
THE Capital One Venture Card!
FOR ANY FLIGHT, ANY TIME!
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE!
HOW ILLUMINATING.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
LET ME GUESS, AM I
ON THE NAUGHTY LIST AGAIN?
HO HO HO!
LET ME GUESS, AM I
ON THE NAUGHTY LIST AGAIN?
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
♪ SILENT NIGHT HOLY NIGHT
♪ ALL IS CALM ALL IS BRIGHT
♪ ROUND YON VIRGIN MOTHER AND
CHILD ♪
♪ HOLY INFANT SO TENDER AND
BRIGHT ♪
♪ SLEEP IN HEAVENLY PEACE
SLEEP IN HEAVENLY PEACE ♪
>>> THAT IS FROM "SATURDAY NIGHT
LIVE" LAST NIGHT.
SOMBER TRIBUTE TO THE VICTIMS IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THE TRAGEDY IS TOUGH FOR THE
ENTIRE COMMUNITY AND THOSE NOT
DIRECTLY AFFECTED STILL WANT TO
MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
YESTERDAY I SPOKE WITH TWO WOMEN
WHO ARE TRYING TO DO JUST THAT.
BEFORE YOU ROLL IT, I WANT TO
TELL YOU, THAT THOSE WOMEN SAW
ME ON TELEVISION, WAS WATCHING
CNN AND THEY WROTE ME A NOTE.
AND I WILL EXPLAIN TO YOU WHAT
THIS NOTE SAYS AFTER YOU HEAR
FROM THEM.
HERE IT IS.
>> WHEN YOU CAME UP TO TALK TO
ME, YOU LADIES, YOU COULD BARELY
GET THE WORDS OUT.
>> THIS IS -- THERE ARE NO
WORDS.
THERE ARE NO WORDS.
EVEN RIGHT NOW WE KNOW THAT
FAMILIES ARE CRYING TOGETHER,
TRYING TO GET THROUGH DAY TO
DAY, AND WE FEEL THAT SINCE WE
WEREN'T DIRECTLY IMPACTED, WE
FEEL LIKE WE WANT TO BE ABLE TO
USE OUR VOICES TO SAY THINGS WE
KNOW PEOPLE ARE GOING TO BE
SAYING FOR A LONG TIME.
AFTER THE CAMERAS ARE GONE.
SOMETIMES IT'S AFTER THE CAMERAS
ARE GONE, THAT THINGS STOP
WORKING AND MOTION STOPS.
>> FOR YOU?
YOU'VE BEEN CRYING THE ENTIRE
TIME YOU'RE STANDING HERE.
>> THERE ARE NO WORDS.
THERE ARE NO ADEQUATE WORDS TO
DESCRIBE WHAT HAS HAPPENED HERE.
AND HOW CHILDREN AND PARENTS AND
GRANDPARENTS AND UNCLES AND
AUNTS AND PEOPLE WHO LIVE FAR
AWAY WHO JUST KNOW THAT WE ARE
HERE, THERE ARE NO WORDS.
AND THIS CAN HAPPEN TO ANYONE,
ANYWHERE.
WE NEED TO MAKE OUR CHILDREN
FEEL SAFE TO GO BACK TO SCHOOL.
AND I WANT TO KNOW HOW WE CAN DO
THAT?
I WANT SOMEONE TO GIVE US AN
ANSWER TO THIS QUESTION.
>> AND BY YOU ASKING, SOME OF
THOSE QUESTIONS MAY BE ANSWERED.
YOU ARE MAKING A DIFFERENCE.
YOU ARE HELPING.
>> WE HOPE SO.
>> THANK YOU.
HOW OLD ARE YOUR KIDS?
>> I HAVE AN 11 AND 14-YEAR-OLD.
>> WHAT GRADES?
>> SIXTH AND NINTH.
>> ARE YOU GOING TO SEND THEM TO
SCHOOL?
>> I'M GOING TO SEND THEM TO
SCHOOL AS LONG AS I CAN TELL
THEM THAT SOMEBODY IS DOING
SOMETHING DIFFERENT TO MAKE THEM
FEEL SAFE.
>> HOW OLD ARE YOUR KIDS?
>> MY DAUGHTER IS 11 AND MY SON
IS 8.
>> ARE YOU GOING TO SEND THEM TO
SCHOOL?
>> IF I FEEL -- IF I FEEL
THEY'RE SAFE.
IF I FEEL THAT THEY'RE SAFE.
>> THANK YOU.
P.
>> IT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
>> THANK YOU.
I'M SO SORRY.
>> I THINK THAT'S ALL.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> CAN I HAVE THIS NOTE?
>> YES.
>> FOR EVERY PARENT?
>> YEAH.
>> THANK YOU, GUYS.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR THE
KIND OF COVERAGE THAT YOU'RE --
YOU'VE BEEN VERY SENSITIVE.
>> SO, LAURA AND SHELLY, THANK
YOU.
THIS IS THE NOTE.
AND I WANTED THEM TO BE ON
CAMERA BECAUSE I THOUGHT THAT
THEIR VOICES NEEDED TO BE HEARD.
THEY DIDN'T WANT TO SHOW THEIR
FULL FACES ON CAMERA BECAUSE
THEY HAD BEEN CRYING FOR 24
HOURS THEY SAID.
WE DON'T LOOK WELL.
SHOOT US FROM THE SIDE.
WE DID THAT.
THE NOTE SAYS, EARLIER YOU ASKED
SOMEONE BEING INTERVIEWED WHAT
WE WOULD WANT OUR COUNTRY TO DO
FOR OUR COMMUNITY.
THIS IS WHAT WE WOULD LIKE.
RIGHT AWAY, WE NEED SPECIFIC
PLANS AND ACTIONS TO IMPROVE
SAFETY FOR OUR CHILDREN AND OUR
SCHOOLS BEFORE THEY ARE EXPECTED
TO RETURN TO SCHOOL.
WE FEEL WE COULD BE -- WE COULD
BETTER ENSURE OUR CHILDREN'S
SAFETY PLACING A PERMANENT
POLICE OFFICER IN EACH OF OUR
SCHOOLS IN NEWTOWN SO THEY WILL
KNOW SOMEONE IS THERE FOR THE
PURPOSE OF PROTECTING THEIR
SCHOOL.
THEY NEED TO FEEL SAFE AND TO BE
SAFE, BE IN CAPITAL LETTERS, BE
SAFE AS SAFE AS POSSIBLE.
BUT EQUALLY IMPORTANT, ARE
ACTIONS TOO.
ONCE AND FOR ALL, FIND WAYS TO
MAKE THESE ACTS NEARLY
IMPOSSIBLE TO CARRY OUT IN THE
FUTURE.
THESE ARE THE ONLY WAYS THAT
THIS TRAGEDY CAN LEAD TO
ANYTHING POSITIVE.
IT IS OUR RESPONSIBILITY TO DO
THIS FOR THESE VICTIMS AND FOR
ALL OF US.
SINCERELY.
SO THANK YOU, LADIES, FOR THAT
AND I THINK THE ENTIRE COUNTRY
HEAR YOUR WORDS RIGHT NOW.
I WANT TO BRING IN CLINICAL
PSYCHOLOGIST DR. JEFF GARRDEER,
IT'S HARD TO TELL WOMEN LIKE I
SPOKE TO NOT TO WORRY, NOT TO
WORRY ABOUT SENDING THEIR KIDS
TO SCHOOL IN THE FUTURE.
FEAR MAY BE A CONSTANT FOR THEM
NOW.
HOW DO WE EASE THEIR WORRIES IN
THIS MOMENT?
>>
>> WELL FIRST OF ALL.
I WANT TO PERSONALLY THANK YOU,
DON, FOR THE SENSITIVE COVERAGE
THAT YOU'VE GIVEN AND BEING
AWARE THAT WE CAN'T IN ANY WAY,
SHALL SHOOTER, MAKE HIM SOME
SORT OF AN HISTORICAL FIGURE.
BECAUSE OTHER PEOPLE WILL FOLLOW
THAT AND THAT'S BEEN PART OF THE
PROBLEM, SO THANK YOU FOR THAT.
>> FIRSTnd FOREMOST, YOU'RE
CORRECT.
FEAR IS GOING TO BE PART OF
THEIR LIVES, NOT FOREVER.
BUT WE NEED TO REASSURE THOSE
CHILDREN THERE IN NEWTOWN, THAT
THEY ARE SAFE.
THEY MUST RETURN TO THAT SCHOOL,
BECAUSE IF THEY AVOID IT, THEN
IT WILL BECOME WHAT WE CALL IN
PSYCHOLOGY, APHOBIC RESPONSE.
SO FIRST AND FOREMOST.
THERE SHOULD BE A POLICE
OFFICER, A LAW ENFORCEMENT, IN
EACH ONE OF THOSE SCHOOLS THERE
FOR JUST A TEMPORARY AMOUNT OF
TIME.
JUST SO THEY FEEL SAFE.
SECONDLY, PARENTS NEED TO GO IN
WITH THE CHILDREN, EVERY DAY,
THROUGH THE HOLIDAYS, AND AFTER,
PROBABLY THROUGH JANUARY.
OR HAVE ADULTS THERE THAT ARE
TRAINED TO BE WITH THOSE KIDS.
AND TO REASSURE THEM, THAT
THEY'RE SAFE.
THERE NEEDS TO BE SUPPORT
GROUPS, MOBILE CRISIS UNITS,
THAT ARE PART OF THE FABRIC OF
THOSE SCHOOLS THERE.
AGAIN, EVERY DAY.
THEY NEED TO USE THE HOLIDAYS,
THE RELIGIOUS HOLIDAYS TO
REMEMBER THOSE THAT HAVE BEEN
LOST.
TO CONTINUE GRIEVING THEIR LOSS.
TO BE ABLE TO TALK ABOUT WHAT
THAT FEELS.
AND FINALLY, WE NEED TO GET THEM
TO HELP ONE ANOTHER.
GET THE KIDS TO HELP ONE
ANOTHER.
TO EMPOWER THEM.
SO THEY DON'T HAVE TO GIVE IN
COMPLETELY TO THE ANXIETY.
AND THERE WILL BE THE PTSD.
NO DOUBT ABOUT THAT.
WITH SO MANY OF THEM.
AS WE ADDRESS THEIR ISSUES,
RIGHT NOW, THE PROGNOSIS WILL BE
BETTER.
>> I WENT UP TO THE CAR AND I
MET THE KIDS AND SAW THE KIDS.
I COULD JUST ONLY IMAGINE IN
THOSE LITTLE VOICES, THOSE KIDS
SAYING MOMMY.
DADDY.
I DON'T WANT TO GO TO SCHOOL.
HOW, WHAT IF SOMEONE COMES INTO
MY SCHOOL.
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO A CHILD WHO
IS ASKING THAT?
>> YOU TELL THAT CHILD THAT YOU
TOTALLY UNDERSTAND THAT THEY ARE
AFRAID.
AND THAT YOU, AS THE PARENT TO
BE HONEST WITH THEM, ARE AFRAID,
TOO.
BUT IN THIS LIFE, NO MATTER HOW
HORRIFIC THINGS MAY TAKE PLACE,
WE MUST HELP ONE ANOTHER.
AND WE OWE IT TO THOSE KIDS WHO
ARE NO LONGER THERE, BECAUSE
THERE WILL BE SOME SURVIVOR
GUILT.
THAT'S SOMETHING THAT A LOT OF
PEOPLE HAVE NOT TALKED ABOUT.
THE WAY TO ATTACK THAT, THE WAY
TO DEAL WITH IT, IS BY GOING
BACK TO SCHOOL.
SO BEING AS GENTLE AND AS
RESPONSIVE AND AS UNDERSTANDING
AS WE CAN, WITH OUR CHILDREN AND
UNDERSTANDING THAT FEAR, BUT
TAKING THEM BY THE HAND, NOT
FORCING THEM, BUT TOGETHER,
GOING IN, AND SAYING, OKAY, I
WILL HELP YOU, BUT YOU HELP MOM
AND DAD, TO BE ABLE TO DEAL WITH
THIS, LET'S GO INTO THIS SCHOOL
TOGETHER.
LET'S GO AND GET THIS EDUCATION,
>> GREAT ADVICE, JEFF GUARDIER,
APPRECIATE IT AS ALWAYS.
>> WE'RE ALL GRIEVING FOR
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE ALL GRIEVING AND WHEN WE
RETURN, THE SIGNS OF SUPPORT,
THE WORDS OF ENCOURAGEMENT AND A
MEMORIAL TO THE VICTIMS, WE'LL
SHOW IT TO YOU.
THE USUAL, BOB?
NOT TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
BOB HAS AFIB:
ATRIAL FIBRILLATION NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
A CONDITION THAT PUTS HIM
AT GREATER RISK FOR A STROKE.
[ GPS ] TURN LEFT.
I DON'T THINK SO.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR YEARS, BOB TOOK WARFARIN,
AND MADE A MONTHLY TRIP TO THE
CLINIC TO GET HIS BLOOD TESTED.
BUT NOT ANYMORE.
BOB'S DOCTOR RECOMMENDED
A DIFFERENT OPTION:
ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
XARELTO® IS THE FIRST AND ONLY
ONCE-A-DAY PRESCRIPTION
BLOOD THINNER
FOR PATIENTS WITH AFIB
NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
THAT DOESN'T REQUIRE
ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING.
LIKE WARFARIN,
XARELTO® IS PROVEN EFFECTIVE
TO REDUCE THE RISK
OF AN AFIB-RELATED STROKE.
THERE IS LIMITED DATA
ON HOW THESE DRUGS COMPARE
WHEN WARFARIN IS WELL MANAGED.
NO ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING
MEANS BOB CAN SPEND HIS
EXTRA TIME HOWEVER HE LIKES.
NEW ZEALAND!
XARELTO®
IS JUST ONE PILL A DAY,
TAKEN WITH THE EVENING MEAL.
AND WITH
NO DIETARY RESTRICTIONS,
BOB CAN EAT THE HEALTHY FOODS
HE LIKES.
DO NOT STOP TAKING
XARELTO® RIVAROXABAN
WITHOUT TALKING TO THE DOCTOR
WHO PRESCRIBES IT FOR YOU.
STOPPING MAY INCREASE YOUR RISK
OF HAVING A STROKE.
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU DEVELOP ANY SIGNS
OR SYMPTOMS OF BLEEDING,
LIKE UNUSUAL BRUISING
OR TINGLING.
YOU MAY HAVE A HIGHER RISK
OF BLEEDING
IF YOU TAKE XARELTO®
WITH ASPIRIN PRODUCTS,
NSAIDS OR BLOOD THINNERS.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE TAKING XARELTO®
IF YOU CURRENTLY HAVE
ABNORMAL BLEEDING.
XARELTO® CAN CAUSE BLEEDING,
WHICH CAN BE SERIOUS,
AND RARELY MAY LEAD TO DEATH.
YOU ARE LIKELY TO BRUISE
MORE EASILY ON XARELTO®,
AND IT MAY TAKE LONGER
FOR BLEEDING TO STOP.
TELL YOUR DOCTORS
YOU ARE TAKING XARELTO®
BEFORE ANY PLANNED MEDICAL
OR DENTAL PROCEDURES.
BEFORE STARTING XARELTO®,
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ANY CONDITIONS,
SUCH AS KIDNEY, LIVER
OR BLEEDING PROBLEMS.
READY TO CHANGE YOUR ROUTINE?
ASK YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
FOR MORE INFORMATION
INCLUDING COST SUPPORT OPTIONS,
CALL 1-888-XARELTO
OR VISIT GOXARELTO.COM.
>>> THIS TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN HAS
BROUGHT PEOPLE TOGETHER TO MOURN
AND TO COMFORT ONE ANOTHER.
THROUGH WORDS AND MEMORIALS WE
ARE FEELING THE HEARTFELT
EMOTION FLOWING THROUGH THIS
TOWN AND AROUND THE COUNTRY.
AND AS WE END THIS HOUR, WE PAY
TRIBUTE TO THOSE WHO LOST THEIR
LIVES WAY TOO SOON.
♪
>> JUST A TRAGIC, TRAGIC
SITUATION FOR THE TEACHERS, THE
PRINCIPALS, AND THOSE ANGELS,
ALL I KEEP THINKING ABOUT IS
THOSE ANGELS.
♪
>>> WHEN THINGS HAPPEN TO YOUR
CHILDREN, AND TO OTHER PEOPLE'S
CHILDREN, I CAN'T LOOK AT MY
CHILDREN'S FACES NOT WITHOUT
SEEING THE FACES OF EVERY ONE OF
THEIR SCHOOLMATES.
♪