FAMILIES HAVE BEEN DAMAGED OR
DESTROYED.
>>> THE FIRST ROURND OF VOTING
ON A NEW CONSTITUTION TO EGYPT
IS OVER.
ROUND TWO HAPPENS NEXT WEEKEND.
EGYPT'S RULING FREEDOM AND
JUSTICE PARTY SAYS MOST PEOPLE
THAT WENT TO THE POLLS THIS
WEEKEND VOTED IN FAVOR OF THE
DRAFT CHARTER.
RIGHTS GROUP SAY THERE HAVE BEEN
COMPLAINTS OF VOTER
INTIMIDATION, BRIBERY AND OTHER
VIOLATIONS.
>>> BACK AT HOME AND REALLY BACK
AT HOME THIS MOM IS FROM
AFGHANISTAN BACK FROM THE WAR,
AND SHE GAVE HER KIDS AN EARLY
HOLIDAY SURPRISE.
WATCH.
>> PULL THOSE BLINDFOLDS OFF,
GUYS.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN, PLEASE
WELCOME PETTY OFFICER ISSA.
SHE'S BEEN IN AFGHANISTAN.
>> JUST IN TIME FOR THE
HOLIDAYS.
I'LL HAVE MORE NEWS FROM AROUND
THE WORLD IN 15 MINUTES.
OUR COVERAGE OF THE NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT SHOOTING CONTINUES
RIGHT NOW.
>>> GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE.
I'M JOHN BERMAN.
>> I'M KATE BOLDUAN.
WE WANT TO WELL KOOM VIEWERS
FROM THE UNITED STATES AND THOSE
JOINING US FROM AROUND THE WORLD
THIS MORNING.
YOU'RE WATCHING OUR SPECIAL
COVERAGE OF THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL SHOOTING HERE IN NEWTOWN.
WE'RE LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> HERE IN NEWTOWN THE PRESIDENT
WILL BE COMING LATER TODAY.
HE'S EXPECTED TO MEET WITH SOME
OF THE VICTIMS OF THE FAMILIES
AND HE WILL SPEAK AT A VIGIL
TONIGHT REMEMBERING THE VICTIMS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SPOKE ABOUT THE
HEA
HEARTBREAK HOURS AFTER THE
SHOOTING ON FRIDAY AND AGAIN
DURING HIS WEEKLY ADDRESS
YESTERDAY.
NOW, OF COURSE, WE HAVE THE
NAMES OF ALL THE VICTIMS IN THIS
SHOOTING.
THERE WERE 20 CHILDREN, ALL OF
THEM WERE JUST 6 OR 7 YEARS OLD.
THERE'S BEEN A FUND SET UP TO
HELP THE FAMILIES OF THE
VICTIMS.
HERE'S THE ADDRESS IF YOU'D LIKE
TO SEND A DONATION, THE SANDY
HOOK SCHOOL SUPPORT FUND, 39
MAIN STREET IN NEWTOWN, THE ZIP
CODE IS 06470.
>> MEANWHILE, INVESTIGATORS HERE
IN NEWTOWN ARE TRYING TO PIECE
IT ALTOGETHER.
THEY FOUND MORE INFORMATION ON
THE SHOOTER, BUT STILL NO
MOTIVATE.
WE GET MORE NOW FROM CNN
NATIONAL CORRESPONDENT SUSAN
CANDIOTTI FOLLOWING THE
INVESTIGATION.
>> Reporter: INVESTIGATORS ARE
LEARNING MORE EACH DAY THAT MAY
EXPLAIN WHAT LED 20-YEAR-OLD AID
DAM LANZA TO LAUNCH A VICIOUS
ATTACK ON YOUNG CHILDREN AND
ADULTS AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> OUR INVESTIGATORS AT THE
CRIME SCENE, THE SCHOOL, AND
SECONDARILY AT THE SECONDARY
CRIME SCENE THAT WE DISCUSSED
WHERE THE FEMALE WAS LOCATED
DECEASED DID PRODUCE SOME VERY
GOOD EVIDENCE IN THIS
INVESTIGATION THAT OUR
INVESTIGATORS WILL BE ABLE TO
USE AND HOPEFULLY PAINT A
COMPLETE PICTURE AS TO HOW AND
MORE IMPORTANTLY WHY THIS
OCCURRED.
>> POLICE WON'T SAY WHAT THE
EVIDENCE IS.
HOWEVER, INVESTIGATORS HAVE BEEN
CHECKING OUT GUN RANGES AND
SPORTING GOODS STORES.
THEY FOLLOWED A LEAD THE SHOOTER
TRIED TO BUY A GUN TUESDAY AT
THIS LOCATION.
AFTER SEARCHING STORE
SURVEILLANCE VIDEOS, THE TIP
DIDN'T PAN OUT.
>> TO DATE ATF HAD NOT UNCOVERED
ANY INFORMATION THAT WOULD
SUBSTANTIATE THE FACT HE TRIED
TO ACQUIRE GUNS RECENTLY.
WE'RE OUT THERE ACTIVELY
INVESTIGATING.
>> Reporter: FEDERAL GUN AGENTS
ALSO SAID THEY RECOVERED WEAPONS
AT THE HOME THE SHOOTER SHARED
WITH HIS MOTHER.
SOURCES SAY THREE MORE GUNS WERE
FOUND.
THESE THREE RIFLE MODELS ALL
OLDER.
THEY'RE BEING TRACED.
AT LEAST ONE HAS BEEN CONNECTED
TO THE MOTHER.
THREE MORE WEAPONS WERE
DISCOVERED WITH THE SHOOTER IN A
CLASSROOM WHERE HE TOOK HIS OWN
LIFE.
ACCORDING TO LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS THE TWO HANDGUNS AND
SEMI-AUTOMATIC LONG RUN CALLED A
BUSHMASTER WERE CALLBOUGHT LEGA.
THEY SAY IT WAS USED TO KILL
SEVERAL VICTIMS.
>> I ONLY DID 7 AUTOPSIES.
THE VICTIMS RANGED FROM 3 TO 11
WOUNDS A PIECE AND ONLY TWO ARE
CLOSE RANGE SHOOTING.
ALL THE SHOOTING AT IN THE TIME
WERE CAUSED BY THE LONG WEAPON.
>> SUSAN CANDIOTTI IS JOINING US
LIVE.
WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT WHAT
INVESTIGATORS ARE LOOKING INTO
TODAY AND WHAT THEY'RE DOING
TODAY?
>> WELL, WE KNOW THAT THEY WILL
BE CONTINUING TO POUND THE
STREETS CHASING DOWN MORE
LEADING THEY TELL US.
FOR EXAMPLE, GOING TO MORE GUN
STORES AND MORE GUN RANGES TO
SEE WHETHER THE SUSPECTED
SHOOTER IN THIS CASE SPENT IN
TIME THERE IN THE DAYS LEADING
UP TO THE SHOOTING.
ULTIMATELY TO TRY TO LEARN WHAT
WAS IN HIS MIND TO MAKE HIM
TARGET SO MANY INNOCENT LIVES.
BACK TO YOU.
>> SUSAN CANDIOTTI, THANK YOU SO
MUCH.
>> FOR A LOT OF PEOPLE RIGHT
NOW, OF COURSE, THE BIGGEST
QUESTION IS WHY?
WHY DID THE SHOOTER KILL THIS
MOTHER AND THEN WALK INTO THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND KILL 26
MORE PEOPLE INCLUDING 20
CHILDREN, ALL 6 AND 7 YEARS OLD.
BRIAN TODD SPOKE WITH SOME
PEOPLE WHO KNEW THE QUIET
20-YEAR-OLD.
BRIAN TRIED TO DIG FOR SOME
ANSWERS.
>> Reporter: HIS MOTIVATE FOR
THIS UNSPEAKABLE ACT IS STILL
NOT CLEAR.
LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS SAY
THAT.
IN DIGGING FOR DETAILS ABOUT
SHOOTER ADAM LANZA AND HIS
FAMILY ACCOUNTING EMERGE THAT
ARE CONFUSING AND CONFLICTING.
A NEIGHBOR WHO KNEW HIM IN
RECENT YEARS DESCRIBES HIM AS
TROUBLED BUT LISTEN TO THIS
ACCOUNT FROM A YOUNG MAN THAT
KNEW HIM.
>> HE WAS JUST A KID.
>> JUST A KID?
>> JUST A KID.
>> NEVER ANTISOCIAL?
>> NO.
>> TROUBLEMAKER?
>> NO, DEFINITELY NOT.
>> NOTICEABLE?
DID HE BLEND INTO THE
BACKGROUND.
>> YEAH.
NOTHING THAT WOULD WARRANT ANY
OF THIS.
>> RYAN CRAFT SAYS HE BABY SATS
ADAM ABOUT TEN YEARS AGO WHEN HE
WAS TEN AND HE WAS 15.
HE DESCRIBED HIM AS FOCUSED,
QUIET, INTROVERTED.
HE NEVER SAW EVIDENCE OF VIE
BENS BUT SAID LANZA DID THROW
THE OCCASIONAL TEMPER TANTRUM.
>> HE WOULDN'T LIKE THAT AND HE
WOULD NOT WANT TO STOP WATCHING
TV.
I GUESS AT 10 YEARS OLD MOST ARE
OUT OF THAT PHASE, AND THAT
WASN'T THE CASE FOR ADAM.
>> CRAFT WAS ONLY A YEAR OLDER
THAN ADAM'S OLDER BROTHER RYAN.
HE SAYS THEIR MOTHER TOLD THEM
TO LET RYAN DO WHATEVER HE
WANTED, BUT AS FOR ADAM --
>> WHAT I REMEMBER CLEARLY IS
THAT NANCY ALWAYS ASKED ME TO
ALWAYS BE WITH HIM IN THE ROOM
NO MATTER WHAT.
DON'T GO TO THE BATHROOM, DON'T
EVER LEAVE HIM WITHOUT
SUPERVISION.
>> CRAFT SAYS ADAM HAD A
CONTENTIOUS RELATIONSHIP WITH
HIS MOTHER, NANCY.
SHE SPLIT FROM THE FATHER WHO IS
DESCRIBED BY THE JOB NETWORKING
WEBSITE LINKED IN AT TAX
DIRECTOR AT GE FINANCIAL
SERVICES.
CRAFT SAYS NANCY WAS AN ENGAGED
MOTHER ALWAYS SETTING UP PLAY
DATES AND TAKING PART IN
ACTIVITIES.
NEIGHBORS AND FRIENDS SAID SHE
ENJOYED GARDENING AND TOOK TIME
OFF FROM A JOB IN FINANCE.
>> JUST LIKE ANYBODY ELSE IN
THIS NEIGHBORHOOD.
DECORATE THE HOUSE AND THE HOUSE
WAS ALWAYS, YOU KNOW, PRISTINE.
SHE WAS LIKE ANY OTHER
HOUSEWIFE.
>> BUT LIKE HER SON, THERE ARE
GAPS IN NANCY'S STORY THAT STILL
NEED TO BE FILLED IN.
SHE OWNED THE WEAPONS THAT ADAM
LANZA USED IN THE KILLINGS
INCLUDING A SEMI-AUTOMATIC RIFLE
AND IT'S NOT CLEAR WHY SHE
PURCHASED THEM.
BRIAN TODD, CNN, WASHINGTON.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
MANY HERE IN NEWTOWN ARE HEADING
TO CHURCH SERVICES THIS MORNING
TO SEEK COMFORT AND MOURN THE
LOSS OF THEIR LOVED ONES.
WE KNOW 12 LITTLE GIRLS AND 8
BOYS WERE SHOT TO DEATH INSIDE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
ALL OF THEM WERE EITHER 6 OR 7
YEARS OLD.
>> AMONG THEM WAS E EMILIE PARK.
SHE WAS AN EXCEPTIONAL ARTIST
THAT CARRIED AROUND ARTISTS AND
PENCILS.
HER FATHER SAID HE GAVE HER A
GOOD-BYE KISS THE LAST TIME HE
SAW HER ALIVE.
>> SIX ADULTS LOST THEIR LIVES
IN THIS TRAGEDY BETWEEN 27 AND
56 YEARS OLD.
THAT INCLUDES 47-YEAR-OLD
PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG WHO
WAS MARRIED AND HAD TWO
DAUGHTERS AND THREE
STEPDAUGHTERS.
ONE PARENT SAID HOCHSPRUNG WAS
ALWAYS SMILING.
>> THE PSYCHOLOGIST HAD A
HISTORY OF WORKING WITH DISABLED
ADULTS.
SHE WAS MARRIED FOR 30 YEARS AND
LOVED TO GARDEN.
30-YEAR-OLD LAUREN RUSSO WAS
HIRED AS A PERMANENT SUBSTITUTE
TEACHER.
HER MOTHER SAID SHE ALWAYS
DREAMED OF TEACHING AND WILL
MISS HER TERRIBLY AND TAKE
COMFORT KNOWING SHE HAD ACHIEVED
THAT DREAM.
>> THE WHOLE TOWN IS GRIEVING
FOR THESE VICTIMS.
THE WHOLE WORLD IS GRIEVING FOR
THESE VICTIMS.
EVEN AS THEIR OWN CHILDREN TRY
TO COME TO GRIPS WITH THE HORROR
OF WHAT HAS HAPPENED HERE.
WE HAVE MORE ON THE STRUGGLE TO
COPE WITH THIS TRAGIC LOSS.
>> IT'S JUST SO SAD HOW QUICKLY
ALL THAT CAN BE TAKEN AWAY FROM
YOU IN A HEARTBEAT.
>> Reporter: GRIEF HAS SETTLED
IN FOR THE PARENTS.
>> IT'S JUST SO SENSELESS.
>> Reporter: RATHER THAN DO
NOTHING, LAURA CAN AT LEAST LAY
FLOWERS AND BE GRATEFUL THAT HER
OWN CHILDREN DON'T SEEM TO
UNDERSTAND.
A LUXURY OF THE VERY YOUNG THAT
MOST DON'T HAVE.
A SMALL COMMUNITY THEY ALL SEEM
TO KNOW A VICTIM, SOME DIRECTLY.
>> LAST NIGHT WE -- IT WAS
UNUSUAL, BECAUSE THEY DIDN'T
RESPOND ON THE PHONE CALLS AND
MESSAGES.
LAST NIGHT WE SIMPLY CALLED.
IT'S THE WORST.
>> Reporter: TRYING TO COPE AND
CONNECT, SIGNS ARE EVERYWHERE IN
THE TOWN'S CENTER, THIS ONE
MARKED EAST LOST VICTIM COUNTING
UP TO 27 INCLUDING THE SHOOTER'S
MOTHER ANOTHER REMINDED IT
WASN'T JUST CHILDREN LOST.
MANDY IS THINKING OF THE
PRINCIPAL.
HER 9-YEAR-OLD SON AT THE
SCHOOL.
>> WE MOVED HERE IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE SCHOOL YEAR AND SHE WAS
SO KIND TO MY SON.
>> DAVID KING'S DAUGHTER WENT TO
PRESCHOOL WITH THE CHILDREN AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
>> I'M JUST AFRAID TO LOOK AT IT
TO RECOGNIZE AND SEE THE NAMES
OF OUR LITTLE ONE'S PLAYMATES.
>> Reporter: HE SENT HIS
DAUGHTER TO A DIFFERENT ELEMENT
ISRAEL SCHOOL, A STROKE OF FATE
ON A DAY WHEN PARENTS LOOK FOR
ANSWERS WHERE THERE ARE NONE.
>> IT'S HEART-WRENCHING RIGHT
NOW.
IT'S NOT EASY TO SWALLOW WHAT'S
GOING ON IN MY BACKYARD.
>> WE'VE SEEN MANY MAKESHIFT
MEMORIALS HONORING VICTIMS
REALLY EVERYWHERE THROUGHOUT THE
TOWN AND MANY OTHER TOWNS.
LATER TODAY THERE'S ANOTHER
VIGIL FOR THE VICTIMS, AND
AGAIN, PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL BE
HERE TO SPEAK AT THAT EVENT.
FOR MORE INFORMATION ON HOW YOU
CAN HELP THOSE AFFECTED BY THE
SHOOTING, YOU CAN GO TO C
CNN.COM/IMPACT.
>> WE'RE GOING SOV OTHER NEWS
AFTER THE BREAK, AND THERE IS A
LOT GOING ON IN THE WORLD
INCLUDING NEWS OF A POSSIBLE
NOMINATION FOR SECRETARY OF
STATE.
WE WILL HAVE THAT NEWS WHEN WE
COME BACK.
[ Woman ] DEAR CAT, YOUR HAIR
MIXES WITH POLLEN AND DUST.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
REFLECTION.
THE NATION REMEMBERING THE
VICTIMS OF THIS CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
EVERYONE DOING IT IN THEIR OWN
WAY, BUT SHOCK WAVES FROM THIS
SENSELESS SCHOOL MASSACRE THAT
LEFT 20 CHILDREN AND 6 ADULTS
LED, THE SHOCKWAVES ARE FELT FAR
BEYOND OUR BORDERS.
MANY WORLD LEADERS OFFERING
THEIR CONDOLENCES.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA, THE BEREAVED
FAMILIES, THE PEOPLE OF AMERICA,
THE PEOPLE OF ISRAEL GRIEVE WITH
YOU.
>> IT IS ALMOST BEYOND
COMPREHENSION THAT SUCH A HAPPY
PLACE COULD BE REDUCED TO A
PLACE OF DEATH AND TERROR, BUT
THAT IS WHAT WE HAVE SEEN TODAY.
OUR HEART-FELT SYMPATHIES GO TO
THOSE FAMILIES WHO HAVE LOST A
CHILD, TO THOSE FAMILIES THAT
HAVE LOST A LOVED ONES AND THOSE
FAMILIES NOW TRYING TO COUNSEL
THEIR YOUNG CHILDREN WITNESS TO
SUCH SHOCKING SCENES AND WOULD
BE SO DISTRESSED AS A RESULT.
>> IN BRAZIL 26 CROSSES WERE
PLACED IN THE SAND ON RIO
DEJANNERO ON THE FAMOUS BEACH
ALL THE WAY UP IN CONNECTICUT.
WE'LL BRING MUCH MORE ON THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING TRAGEDY, BUT
FIRST A LOT OF OTHER NEWS.
LET'S GO TO STRIK FOR BLACKWELL
FOR THE LATEST ON ALL THE OTHER
STORIES.
GOOD MORNING.
>> GOOD MORNING.
16 DAYS BEFORE THE U.S. GOES
OVER THE FISCAL CLIFF, BUT THERE
COULD BE A DEAL IN WASHINGTON.
A SOURCE CLOSE TO THE TALKS
TELLS CNN HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER IS WILLING TO HIKE TAXES
ON THE WEALTHIEST AMERICANS.
THAT'S SOMETHING THE PRESIDENT
SAYS MUST BE PART OF ANY PLAN.
SPEAKER BOEHNER PREVIOUSLY
CALLED TAX INCREASES ON THE TOP
2% A NONSTARTER.
>>> THIS WEEK PRESIDENT OBAMA IS
EXPECTED TO NOMINATE SENATOR
JOHN KERRY AS HIS NEXT SECRETARY
OF STATE.
THE MASSACHUSETTS DEMOCRAT HAS
SERVED IN THE SENATE FOR ALMOST
30 YEARS.
HE'S BEEN CHAIRMAN OF THE SENATE
FOREIGN RELATIONS COMMITTEE FOR
THE PAST FOUR YEARS.
THE MASSACHUSETTS GOVERNOR
DUVALL PATRICK WOULD NAME A
REPLACEMENT UNTIL A SPECIAL
ELECTION.
>>> OUTGOING SECRETARY OF STATE
HILLARY CLINTON IS RESTING AT
HOME AFTER SUFFERING A
CONCUSSION.
SHE'S BEEN BATTLING A STOMACH
VIRUS AND FAINTED AFTER BECOMING
DEHYDRATED.
HER OFFICE SAID IT'S NOT SEVERE
BUT WILL SKIP HE HER APPEARANCE
IN FRONT OF HOUSE FOREIGN
AFFAIRS COMMITTEE THIS WEEK.
SHE WAS SCHEDULED TO TESTIFY ON
THURSDAY ABOUT THE ATTACK ON THE
U.S. CONSULATE IN BENGHAZI,
LIBYA ON SEPTEMBER 11th.
>>> MORE GUNSHOTS.
THIS TIME THE FRIGHTENING
INCIDENT WAS AT A SHOPPING MALL
PARKING LOT AT NEWPORT BEACH,
CALIFORNIA.
A MAN IN THE PARKING LOT FIRED
50 SHOTS IN THE AIR.
THIS HAPPENED YESTERDAY.
STORES THAT WERE FILLED WITH
WITH HOLIDAY SHOPPERS, THOSE
DOORS WERE LOCKED QUICKLY.
NO ONE WAS HIT BY THE BULLETS,
BUT ONE PERSON SUFFERED MINOR
INJURIES GETTING OUT OF THE WAY.
THE SUSPECT IS IN CUSTODY, BUT
POLICE HAVE NOT GIVEN A REASON
FOR THE SHOOTING.
>>> NELSON MANDELA IS RECOVERING
AFTER SURGERY TO REMOVE
GALLSTONES.
THEY SAY THE PROCEDURE WAS
SUCCESSFUL.
THE 94-YEAR-OLD HAS BEEN IN THE
HOSPITAL SINCE LAST WEEKEND
BECAUSE OF AA RECURRING LUNG
INFECTION.
MR. MANDELA WAS AWARDED THE
NOBEL PEACE PRIZE AND SPENT
ALMOST THREE DECADES IN PRISON
FOR OPPOSING APARTHEID.
LET'S GO BACK TO CNN'S JOHN
BERMAN AND KATE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH, VICTOR.
WE'LL SEE YOU AGAIN FOR MORE
NEWS IN A LITTLE BIT.
A 27-YEAR-OLD TEACHER CAME FACE
TO FACE WITH A GUNMAN AT SANDY
HOOK, AND IT'S WHAT SHE DID NEXT
THAT GRATEFUL PARENTS SAY SHAVED
THEIR CHILDREN'S LIVES.
NOW SHE'S REMEMBERED AS A TRUE
HERO.
But when I was in an accident...
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
So I never missed a beat.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
>>> THERE WAS A MOMENT OF
SILENCE LAST NIGHT BEFORE THE
MIAMI HEAT GAME.
THE PLAYERS TOOK THE COURT WITH
THEIR OWN CHILDREN IN HAND.
IT WAS THEIR WAY OF PAYING
TRIBUTE TO THE CHILDREN KILLED
HERE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
ALSO TODAY SEVERAL NFL TEAMS
WILL HONOR THOSE VERY VICTIMS.
THE NEW YORK JETS, THE GIANTS,
AND THE NEW ENGLAND PATRIOTS ARE
ALSO PLANNING TRIBUTES.
ONE OF THE TEACHERS WHO DIED AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IS
BEING HAILED AROUND THE WORLD
FOR HER BRAVERY.
♪ AMAZING GRACE
>> HUNDREDS SANG "AMAZING GRACE"
FOR VICTORIA SOTO IN HER OWN
HOMETOWN OF STRATFORD,
CONNECTIC
CONNECTICUT.
SHE MOVED HER STURNTS AWAY FROM
THE CLASSROOM DOOR.
TO PROTECT THE CHILDREN SHE
FACED THE GUNMAN WHEN HE STORMED
IN.
I SPOKE YESTERDAY WITH TWO
PARENTS WHOSE SON BY WHAT THEY
CALL A MIRACLE MADE IT OUT OF
THAT CLASSROOM AALIVE.
>> WHEN THEY HEARD NOISES THAT
HE DESCRIBED AS INITIALLY THEY
THOUGHT WERE HAMMERS FALLING,
THEN THEY REALIZED THAT IT WAS
GUNSHOT.
AND MISS SOTO, WHO WAS AIDAN'S
TEACH, HAD THE PRESENCE OF MIND
TO MOVE ALL THE CHILDREN TO A
DISTANCE AWAY FROM THE DOOR ON
THE SIDE OF THE ROOM FURTHEST
AWAY FROM THE DOOR.
THAT'S WHEN THE GUNMAN BURST IN,
DID NOT SAY A WORD, NO FACIAL
EXPRESSIONS, AND PROCEEDED TO
SHOOT THEIR TEACHER.
THEY BASICALLY RAN RIGHT NEXT TO
THE GUY AND OUT THE DOOR.
>> THEY RAN PAST THE GUNMAN?
>> THEY RAN PAST THE GUY.
HE'S STILL STANDING IN THE DOOR,
AND THEY RAN PAST HIM AND RAN
DOWN THE HALLWAY.
THEY'RE ONE OF THE CLOSEST ROOMS
TO THE MAIN ENTRANCE, AND AIDAN
WAS -- HAD THE PRESENCE OF MIND
TO HOLD THE DOOR FOR ONE OF HIS
CLASSMATES AND THEN THERE WAS
ANOTHER CLASSMATE THAT WAS A
LITTLE BEHIND AND WAITED FOR HIM
AND THEN THEY ALL RAN TO THE
ROAD, TO THE MAIN ROAD.
>> DO YOU THINK HE KNOWS WHAT
THE -- THAT YOU LIKELY DID
NOT --
>> HE KEEPS ASKING ABOUT HER.
HE'S REASSURING HIMSELF THAT
SHE'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
HE REALLY, REALLY, REALLY CARED
ABOUT HIS TEACHER.
HE WAS VERY CLOSE WITH HER, AND
SHE REALLY LOVED THE CLASS.
HE KEEPS SAYING I REALLY HOPE
SHE'S OKAY.
I HOPE IT'S NOT HER.
HE KNOWS THAT SHE'S BEEN HURT,
BUT HE DOESN'T KNOW THE END
RESULT.
HE KNOWS THE KIDS THAT HE SAW
GETTING SHOT.
HE DOESN'T KNOW THE OUTCOME.
SO I THINK HE'S REASSURING
HIMSELF IN HIS 6-YEAR-OLD MIND,
PROCESSING IT.
I THINK HE'S REASSURING HIMSELF.
I THINK HE'S TELLING HIMSELF
THAT IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
WE HAD TO PUT THE SIGN OUT ON
THE FRONT ASKING PEOPLE NOT TO
RING THE DOORBELL BECAUSE HE
STILL HASN'T INTERNALIZED THE
FACT THAT THIS GUNMAN, BAD GUY
IS GONE.
HE WANTS TO KNOW IF THERE ARE
MORE BAD GUYS IN THE WORLD, AND
I DON'T KNOW HOW TO ANSWER THAT
QUESTION PROPERLY.
SO WHEN SOMEONE RINGS THE
DOORBELL, HE THINKS IT'S HIM
COMING BACK, COMING FOR HIM.
AND SO HE -- SO I THINK OUR
BIGGEST CONCERN NOW IS MAKING
SURE THAT WE HANDLE HIS
SENSITIVE NATURE PROPERLY AND
CAREFULLY AND SUPPORT HIM AND
SUPPORT OUR DAUGHTER, BECAUSE
SHE DOES PROCESS THINGS VERY
DIFFERENTLY THAN HE DOES.
SO THAT'S OUR JOB AS PARENTS
NOW, IS TO STAY CLOSE TO THEM,
HOLD THEM, HUG THEM, LOVE THEM,
AND LET THEM KNOW THAT THEY ARE
SAFE.
>> VICTORIA SOTO'S SISTER AND
COUSIN SAY THEY ARE VERY PROUD
SHE HAD THE INSTINCT TO PROTECT
THEIR STUDENTS THAT FRIDAY
MORNING AND THAT THAT BRINGS
THEM SOME PEACE ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED.
THEY SAY SHE'S A HERO.
A REGULAR GUY
WITH AN IRREGULAR HEARTBEAT.
THE USUAL, BOB?
NOT TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
BOB HAS AFIB:
ATRIAL FIBRILLATION NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
A CONDITION THAT PUTS HIM
AT GREATER RISK FOR A STROKE.
[ GPS ] TURN LEFT.
I DON'T THINK SO.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR YEARS, BOB TOOK WARFARIN,
AND MADE A MONTHLY TRIP TO THE
CLINIC TO GET HIS BLOOD TESTED.
BUT NOT ANYMORE.
BOB'S DOCTOR RECOMMENDED
A DIFFERENT OPTION:
ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
XARELTO® IS THE FIRST AND ONLY
ONCE-A-DAY PRESCRIPTION
BLOOD THINNER
FOR PATIENTS WITH AFIB
NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
THAT DOESN'T REQUIRE
ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING.
LIKE WARFARIN,
XARELTO® IS PROVEN EFFECTIVE
TO REDUCE THE RISK
OF AN AFIB-RELATED STROKE.
THERE IS LIMITED DATA
ON HOW THESE DRUGS COMPARE
WHEN WARFARIN IS WELL MANAGED.
NO ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING
MEANS BOB CAN SPEND HIS
EXTRA TIME HOWEVER HE LIKES.
NEW ZEALAND!
XARELTO®
IS JUST ONE PILL A DAY,
TAKEN WITH THE EVENING MEAL.
AND WITH
NO DIETARY RESTRICTIONS,
BOB CAN EAT THE HEALTHY FOODS
HE LIKES.
DO NOT STOP TAKING
XARELTO® RIVAROXABAN
WITHOUT TALKING TO THE DOCTOR
WHO PRESCRIBES IT FOR YOU.
STOPPING MAY INCREASE YOUR RISK
OF HAVING A STROKE.
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU DEVELOP ANY SIGNS
OR SYMPTOMS OF BLEEDING,
LIKE UNUSUAL BRUISING
OR TINGLING.
YOU MAY HAVE A HIGHER RISK
OF BLEEDING
IF YOU TAKE XARELTO®
WITH ASPIRIN PRODUCTS,
NSAIDS OR BLOOD THINNERS.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE TAKING XARELTO®
IF YOU CURRENTLY HAVE
ABNORMAL BLEEDING.
XARELTO® CAN CAUSE BLEEDING,
WHICH CAN BE SERIOUS,
AND RARELY MAY LEAD TO DEATH.
YOU ARE LIKELY TO BRUISE
MORE EASILY ON XARELTO®,
AND IT MAY TAKE LONGER
FOR BLEEDING TO STOP.
TELL YOUR DOCTORS
YOU ARE TAKING XARELTO®
BEFORE ANY PLANNED MEDICAL
OR DENTAL PROCEDURES.
BEFORE STARTING XARELTO®,
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ANY CONDITIONS,
SUCH AS KIDNEY, LIVER
OR BLEEDING PROBLEMS.
READY TO CHANGE YOUR ROUTINE?
ASK YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
FOR MORE INFORMATION
INCLUDING COST SUPPORT OPTIONS,
CALL 1-888-XARELTO
OR VISIT GOXARELTO.COM.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN DIARRHEA HITS,
KAOPECTATE STOPS IT FAST.
POWERFUL LIQUID RELIEF
SPEEDS TO THE SOURCE.
FAST.
[ Male Announcer ]
STOP THE UH-OH FAST
WITH KAOPECTATE.
>>> WELCOME BACK EVERYONE.
IT'S HALF PAST THE HOUR RIGHT
NOW.
I'M JOHN BERMAN WITH KATE
BUOLDAN.
THIS AFTERNOON PRESIDENT OBAMA
WILL HEAD HERE TO NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT WHERE HE WILL MEET
WITH THE FAMILIES OF THE
VICTIMS.
THE PRESIDENT WILL SPEAK AT A
VIGIL TONIGHT.
12 VICTIMS WERE GIRLS AND 8 WERE
BOYS.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER RELEASED
ALL THE NAMES YESTERDAY, SO, SO
YOUNG.
SIX VICTIMS WERE ADULTS, ALL
WOMEN THAT WORKED AT THE SCHOOL.
THE UNITED WAY SET UP A FUND TO
COLLECT DONATIONS FOR THE
VICTIMS' FAMILY IN THE COMMUNITY
AS A WHOLE, IT'S CALLED THE
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL SUPPORT FUND.
ALL DONATIONS GO DIRECTLY TO
THOSE AFFECTED.
>> WE WANT TO PAY TRIBUTE TO 26
PEOPLE KILLED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
HERE NOW ARE THEIR NAMES AND
AGES.
>> JUST A TRAGIC, TRAGIC
SITUATION FOR THE TEACHERS, THE
PRINCIPALS, AND THOSE ANGELS.
THAT'S ALL I CAN THINK ABOUT, IS
THOSE ANGELS.
♪
>> I MEAN, WHEN THINGS HAPPEN TO
YOUR CHILDREN AND TO OTHER
PEOPLE'S CHILDREN, I CAN'T LOOK
AT MY CHILDREN'S FACES NOW
WITHOUT SEEING THE FACES OF
EVERY ONE OF THEIR SCHOOLMATES.
♪
>>> FOR MORE INFORMATION ON HOW
YOU CAN HELP ALL OF THOSE
AFFECTED BY THIS SHOOTING, YOU
CAN GO TO CNN.COM/IMPACT.
LET'S GO TO VICTOR BLACKWELL IN
ATLANTA WITH A SPECIAL GUEST.
>>> IT'S TIME FOR FACES OF
FAITH.
>>> THIS MORNING WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT TURNING TO FAITH TO FIND
COMFORT IN THE FACE OF
UNIMAGINABLE VIOLENCE.
RABBI LESSER JOINS ME NOW.
HE'S FROM CONGREGATION IN
ATLANTA.
THANKS FOR COMING IN TO SPEAK
WITH US.
THERE ARE SO MANY QUESTIONS AND
SO MANY DIFFICULT CONVERSATIONS.
PEOPLE ARE GOING TO HOUSES OF
WORSHIP.
WHAT COMFORT CAN YOUR FAITH
OFFER IN A TIME LIKE THIS?
>> I THINK AS A COUNTRY WE'RE
GRIEVING WITH THE FAMILIES AND
THIS HORRIBLE TRAGEDY STIRS UP
OUR OWN SENSE OF GRIEF AND THIS
POSSIBILITY OF WHAT IT WOULD
MEAN IF IT HAPPENED IN OUR
COMMUNITY AND FAMILIES.
PEOPLE COMING TOGETHER BRINGS A
GREAT DEAL OF STRENGTH AND
COMFORT.
I THINK PRAYER.
THEY'RE NOT THE ONLY VEHICLE.
IT'S A POWERFUL VEHICLE TO
EXPRESS THOSE REALLY POWERFUL
EMOTIONS THAT GRIEF CAN BRING TO
US.
THE MORE THAT WE GATHER, THE
MORE THAT WE TALK ABOUT THIS, IT
HELPS US SEE THE VALUES WE WANT
TO BRING INTO OUR SOCIETY.
ALL OF THAT FOR ME IS REALLY
POSITIVE STEPS TOWARDS HOW TO
DEAL WITH SUCH AN UNSPEAKABLE
TRAGEDY.
>> THE CHURCH IN NEWTOWN HAS
BEEN OPEN 24 HOURS A DAY.
WE SEE PICTURES OF PACKED
CHURCHES AND VIGILS.
I WANT TO PLAY SOMETHING ROBBIE
PARKER SAID, AND THEN WE'RE
GOING TO DISCUSS IT.
>> THAT FREE AGENCY IS GIVEN TO
ALL OF US TO ACT AND CHOOSE
WHATEVER WE WANT.
GOD CAN'T TAKE THAT AWAY FROM
US.
I KNOW THAT'S SOMETHING HE WAS
GIVEN, AND THAT'S WHAT HE CHOSE
TO DO WITH IT.
I KNOW GOD CAN'T TAKE THAT AWAY.
I'M NOT MAD.
>> THE QUESTION OF FATE AND
DESTINY AND FREE AGENCY, TRY TO
SORT THAT OUT FOR US.
>> FIRST OF ALL, I BELIEVE WE
HAVE FREE WILL, AND THAT WE'VE
BEEN GIVEN ALL THE TOOLS TO
CREATE A SOCIETY THAT PROTECTS
OUR CHILDREN AND CARES FOR OUR
CHILDREN, AND THEN IN SOME WAYS
WE HAVE TO LOOK AT HOW WE HAVE
FAILED WHEN WE HAVE MOMENTS LIKE
THIS.
SO I UNDERSTAND THIS IDEA OF NOT
BEING ANGRY AT GOD.
I WANT TO SAY IT'S OKAY TO BE
ANGRY RIGHT NOW.
WITH GRIEF WE HAVE MANY, MANY
FEELINGS, AND I THINK FAITH CAN
HANDLE ALL OF THEM.
I THINK THAT THIS WASN'T
DESTINED.
THERE ARE THINGS WE COULD HAVE
DONE.
IN SOME WAYS THE PIECE OF GRIEF
THAT IS THE HARDEST IS HOW DO WE
LOOK AT HOW WE'RE RESPONSIBLE.
THAT MAY NOT BE THE FIRST PLACE
WE GO.
RIGHT NOW IT'S REALLY JUST ABOUT
REACHING OUT AND, YOU KNOW,
BLESSING OUR CHILDREN, MAKING
SURE THAT WE'RE ABLE TO PROVIDE
THE SENSE OF SAFETY AND SECURITY
THAT THEY NEED AND FRANKLY WE
NEED AT THIS MOMENT, TOO.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
OUR CONVERSATION IS MORE ABOUT
FAITH.
I WANT TO ASK YOU SOMETHING MIKE
HUCKABEE SAID, I WANT TO TALK
ABOUT THIS, FORMER PASTOR,
FORMER GOVERNOR AND FORMER
PRESIDENTIAL NOMINEE.
HE SAID WE ASK WHY THEY'RE
VIOLENCE IN OUR SCHOOL, BUT WE
SYSTEMICALLY REMOVED GOD FROM
OUR SCHOOLS.
SHOULD WE BE SO SURPRISED
SCHOOLS ARE SUCH A PLACE OF
CARNAGE?
PEOPLE WILL MAKE A SDID
POLITICALLY IF THEY AAGREE OR
NOT, BUT WHAT WOULD YOU SAY THE
RELATIONSHIP IS BETWEEN FAITH
AND VIOLENCE?
CAN YOU PREY AWAY THE TENDENCY
FOR SOMETHING LIKE THIS TO
HAPPEN?
>> I DON'T THINK PRAYER IS THE
ONLY TOOL, AND I THINK OUR
SCHOOLS WOULD BE MUCH BETTER IN
TERMS OF TEACHING OUR CHILDREN
NONVIOLENT COMMUNICATION, WAYS
TO REDUCE BULLYING.
THESE KINDS OF THINGS THAT KEEP
OUR CHILDREN WITH A SENSE OF
SAFETY.
WHEN THEY DO FEEL UNSAFE, THE
WAY THAT THEY CONTINUE TO GROW.
SO FOR ME TEACHING VALUES RATHER
THAN PRAYER.
PRAYER CAN CERTAINLY HELP THAT,
BUT I DON'T THINK THAT'S THE WAY
TO GO BECAUSE OF THE COMPLEXITY
OF FAITH IN THIS COUNTRY.
SHARED CIVIL VALUES, THAT WE
HAVE AS MULTIPLE FAITH HE
PEOPLE.
>> WE HAVE ABOUT 30 SECONDS
LEFT.
THIS IS PARTY SEASON.
LAST NIGHT OF HANUKKAH AND
CHRISTMAS IS A WEEK AWAY.
SOME PEOPLE PROBABLY FEEL GUILTY
CELEBRATING, DANCING WHEN THIS
IS HAPPENING.
WHAT DO YOU TELL THEM?
>> I TELL THEM FROM MY FAITH
TRADITION, JUDAISM SAYS YOU HAVE
TO CLING TO LIFE.
I THINK WE PERHAPS ACKNOWLEDGE
OUR LOSS, THE BUT IT DOESN'T
MEAN WE HAVE TO COMPLETELY
SEPARATE OURSELVES.
PERHAPS THE TIME TO REMOVE
EXCESS FROM OUR SENSE OF
PARTYING AND CONNECT TO THE REAL
SPIRIT OF THESE DAYS THAT TELL
US THAT FAMILY AND A SENSE OF
GRATITUDE FOR WHAT WE HAVE IS
REALLY IMPORTANT.
THAT'S WORTH CELEBRATING IN THE
MIDST OF THIS TRAGIC LOSS.
>> RABBI LESSER, THANK YOU SO
MUCH FOR TALKING WITH US.
FOR MORE STORIES ON FAITH CHECK
OUT OUR WIDELY READ BELIEF BLOG.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH MORE,
LIVE FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
[ Woman ] DEAR CAT, YOUR HAIR
MIXES WITH POLLEN AND DUST.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
But when I was in an accident...
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
So I never missed a beat.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.
>>> THE SHOOTINGS HERE IN
NEWTOWN ARE STIRRING UP MEMORIES
OF ANOTHER HORRIBLE SHOOTING
MASSACRE, THE ONE AT VIRGINIA
TECH UNIVERSITY BACK IN 2007.
IT DOES NOT SEEM IT WAS THAT
MANY YEARS AGO AT THIS APPOINT.
IT SEEMS LIKE JUST YESTERDAY.
PETER REED'S 19-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHTER MARY KAREN REED AND 30
OTHER PEOPLE DIED IN WHAT IS THE
NATION'S WORST SCHOOL SHOOTING,
DEADLIEST SCHOOL SHOOTING.
HE JOINS US FROM OUR BUREAU IN
WASHINGTON.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US THIS
MORNING.
A HORRIBLE REASON AND ORDEAL FOR
US TO BE SPEAKING WITH YOU.
WE APPRECIATE YOUR TIME.
YOU HAVE A UNIQUE PERSPECTIVE WE
ALL WISH NO PARENT HAD.
TELL US A LITTLE BIT IF YOU
COULD WHAT THE PARENTS HERE IN
NEWTOWN MAY BE GOING THROUGH.
NOW IT'S REALLY JUST TWO DAYS
AFTER THIS EVENT.
>> SURE.
FIRST, LET ME SAY FOR ALL THE
FAMILIES AND SURVIVORS FROM
VIRGINIA TECH, WE ALL IDENTIFY
WITH THEM AND PASS OUR
CONDOLENCES AND OUR LOVE AND OUR
BEST WISHES TO THEM AND LET THEM
KNOW WE'RE GOING TO BE THERE FOR
THEM IN WHATEVER WAY WE CAN.
THE FIRST FEW DAYS ARE -- LET ME
ALSO SAY THAT EVERY TRAGEDY IS
INDIVIDUAL AND SPECIFIC, SO WE
DON'T KNOW EXACTLY WHAT THEY'RE
GOING THROUGH.
WE HAVE SOME IDEA WHAT THEY'RE
IF THEIR EXPERIENCE IS SIMILAR
IT TO OURS, THE FIRST FEW DAYS
ARE JUST SURREAL.
YOU CAN'T DESCRIBE THE PIT, I
GUESS, IS THE BEST WORD TO
DESCRIBE THAT YOU DESCEND INTO
IT.
THE ONLY THING THAT KEEPS YOU
GOING IN THE FIRST FEW DAYS IS
THE LOVE OF FRIENDS AND FAMILY.
I'M STRUCK BY HOW THAT COMMUNITY
IS PULLING TOGETHER IN THEIR
HOUSES OF WORSHIP AND JUST THE
STRENGTH OF THE COMMUNITY.
IT SEEMS TO BE CARRYING THEM
THROUGH.
THAT'S GOING TO BE CRITICAL FOR
THEM IN THE NEXT FEW DAYS, WEEKS
AND MONTHS.
ABSOLUTELY.
>> PETER, IT'S REMARKABLE.
THERE'S SO MUCH LOVE IN THIS
TOWN.
THE CHURCHES HAVE SIGNS OUTDOORS
THAT SAY OPEN 24 HOURS.
ONE OF THE THINGS PEOPLE ARE
SAYING, THE FAMILIES OF THE
VICTIMS, IS THAT THEY DON'T WANT
TO BE DEFINED BY THIS SHOOTING.
THEY DON'T WANT THIS TOWN AND
THEIR FAMILIES DEFINED BY THIS
AWFUL EVENT.
HAVING BEEN THROUGH THIS, IS
THAT POSSIBLE, AND HOW DO YOU
ACHIEVE THAT GOAL?
>> WELL, I WAS READING THIS
MORNING A QUOTE FROM EMILIE
PARKER'S FATHER WHERE HE SAID
THAT -- I WAS STRUCK BY HOW
SIMILAR TO THINGS THAT WERE SAID
AND SOME OF US SAID AMONGST
OURSELVES ABOUT VIRGINIA TECH.
INITIALLY FOR THE PUBLIC, I
THINK, MOST OF THE VICTIM NAMES
AND THE FAMILIES WILL BE DEFINED
BY THE TRAGEDY.
I THINK AS THE STORIES OF THESE
CHILDREN AND THEIR TEACHERS
BECOME KNOWN, THEN THAT WILL
CHANGE.
NOW, WITHIN EACH FAMILY AND
WITHIN EACH GROUP CONNECTED TO
EACH INDIVIDUAL, IT'S VERY
PARTICULAR.
IT'S NOT -- YOU'RE NOT DEFINED
BY THE TRAGEDY AND THE NAME.
YOU'RE DEFINED BY THE PARTICULAR
LOSS THAT YOU SUFFERED.
SO IN EACH CASE THAT FAMILY NOW
HAS A HOLE IN IT THAT'S SHAPED
LIKE THAT PERSON THEY LOST.
THAT'S GOING TO GO FORWARD
THROUGH THEIR LIVES.
THE THING THAT THEY'RE GOING TO
HAVE TO LEARN, AS WE'VE ALL HAD
TO LEARN, IS HOW IT TO LIVE
AROUND THAT LOSS.
YOU DON'T MOVE ON FROM IT.
YOU NEVER MOVE ON IT FROM IT.
WHEN PEOPLE SAY THAT, I DON'T
KNOW WHAT THEY'RE THINKING.
YOU CAN MOVE FORWARD AND FIND
WAYS TO MOVE FORWARD AND HONOR
THE MEMORY OF THE PERSON THAT
YOU'VE LOST IN HOW YOU LIVE YOUR
OWN LIFE.
>> ONE THING THAT STRUCK US,
PETER, IS WHEN YOU MENTIONED
ROBBIE PARKER SPEAKING ABOUT HIS
YOUNG, YOUNG DAUGHTER LAST
NIGHT.
HE SAID, I'M NOT MAD.
HE ALSO SENT HIS CONDOLENCES TO
THE FAMILY OF THE SHOOTER.
HE SENT HIS CONDOLENCES FOR THE
FAMILY OF THE ADAM LANZA.
IT STRUCK MANY OF US, THAT
STRENGTH AND HUMILITY.
HOW DO YOU SQUARE THAT WHEN YOU
KNOW THE ANGER I'M SURE MANY ARE
STILL FEELING?
>> WELL, WE HAD SIMILAR EMOTIONS
AND SIMILAR EXPERIENCES.
SO I CAN UNDERSTAND HIS
EXPRESSION OF THAT.
WE HAD SIMILAR FEELINGS FOR THE
FAMILY OF THE PERSON WHO DID
WHAT HE DID AT VIRGINIA TECH.
YOU CANNOT HOLD THE FAMILY
ACCOUNTABLE FOR THE ACTIONS OF
THE INDIVIDUAL, AND THEY SUFFER
A LOSS AS GREAT AND PAINFUL AS
ANY SUFFERED, AND THEY CARRY AN
ADDITIONAL BURDEN BECAUSE JUST
LIKE, YOU KNOW, I WOULD WONDER
OR I'M SURE MR. PARKER WONDERS
WHAT COULD I HAVE DONE TO SAVE
MY CHILD?
THEY WONDER, WHAT COULD WE HAVE
DONE TO MAKE THIS COME OUT
DIFFERENTLY?
THE ANSWER IS, PROBABLY NOTHING.
THERE IS PROBABLY NOTHING THEY
COULD HAVE DONE DIFFERENTLY.
I CAN FULLY UNDERSTAND WHEN HE
SAYS HE MAY BE ANGRY AT OTHER
THINGS, BUT I CAN UNDERSTAND WHY
HE SAYS HE'S NOT ANGRY AT THAT
FAMILY BECAUSE THAT'S -- THAT'S
JUST KIND OF A FRUITLESS EMOTION
AT THAT POINT.
YOU UNDERSTAND THAT THEY'RE
SUFFERING A LOSS AS WELL.
>> WELL, PETER READ, AT THIS
TIME WHEN WE PAY TRIBUTE TO THE
VICTIMS HERE IN CONNECTICUT, WE
ALSO WANT TO PAY TRIBUTE TO YOUR
DAUGHTER, THE DAUGHTER YOU LOST,
19-YEAR-OLD MARY KAREN.
EVERYTHING THAT I HAVE READ AND
HEARD ABOUT HER OVER THE YEARS
IS SHE WAS A VERY WONDERFUL
YOUNG WOMAN WITH A VERY BRIGHT
WOMAN.
AND WE WANT TO PAY A TRIBUTE TO
YOUR FAMILY AS WELL.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR YOUR TIME
TODAY.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> WE'RE GOING TO HAVE MORE NEWS
AFTER THE BREAK INCLUDING A
POSSIBLE MOVE IN WASHINGTON, A
MOVE FOR SENATOR JOHN KERRY
PERHAPS HEADED TO THE STATE
DEPARTMENT.
>>> FIRST, WE WANT TO LISTEN TO
WHAT PRESIDENT OBAMA HAD TO SAY
ABOUT THIS MASS SHOOTING.
LIKE MANY OF US WHEN HE STARTED
TO TALK ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED, THE
PRESIDENT, HE COULD NOT HOLD
BACK THE TEARS.
>> WE'VE ENDURED TOO MANY OF
THESE TRAGEDIES IN THE PAST FEW
YEARS.
I KNOW THERE'S NOT A PARENT IN
AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN, BEAUTIFUL
LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN THE AGES OF
5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM, BIRTHDAYS,
GRADUATIONS, WEDDINGS, KIDS OF
THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS, MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES IT TO
HELPING OUR CHILDREN FULFILL
THEIR DREECAMS.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN FOR THE
PAI
PARENTS OF THE SURVIVORS AS
WELL.
AS BLESSED AS THEY ARE IT TO
HAVE THEIR CHILDREN HOME
TONIGHT, THEY KNOW THEIR
CHILDREN'S INNOCENCE HAS BEEN
TORN AWAY FROM THEM TOO EARLY,
AND THERE ARE NO WORDS TO EASE
THIRP PAIN.
THIS EVENING MICHELLE AND I WILL
DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT IN
AMERICA WILL DO, WHICH IS HUG
OUR CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER
AND TELL THEM THAT WE LOVE THEM
AND REMIND EACH OTHER HOW DEEPLY
WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT THAT CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT.
MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF THE
VICTIMS AND IN THE WORDS OF
SCRIPTURE, HEAL THE
BROKEN-HEARTED AND BIND UP THEIR
WOUNDS.
[ Male Announcer ] Alka-Seltzer
Plus PRESENTS THE Cold Truth.
I HAVE A COLD,
AND I TOOK NYQUIL,
BUT I'M STILL "STUBBED" UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT DOESN'T HAVE A DECONGESTANT.
NO WAY.
[ Male Announcer ] SORRY.
Alka-Seltzer Plus FIGHTS
YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A FAST ACTING
DECONGESTANT
TO RELIEVE YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
[ sighs ] THANKS!
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus.
♪ OH
WHAT A RELIEF IT IS! ♪
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
AND SAVE $1
VISIT Alka-Seltzer ON FACEBOOK.
>>> GOOD MORNING AGAIN FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
JOHN BERMAN HERE WITH KATE
BOULDAN.
IT IS SUNDAY MORNING.
SO MANY PEOPLE IN THIS TOWN NOW
HEADED TO CHURCH SERVICES TO
CONTINUE TO GRIEVE, IT TO MOURNO
REMEMBER.
WE WANT TO PAUSE FOR A MOMENT TO
LOOK AT ALL THE NAMES AND AGES
OF THE 26 PEOPLE KILLED AT THIS
HORRIBLE TRAGEDY AT THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> MUCH MORE AHEAD ON THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING TRAGEDY HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
FIRST LET'S GO TO VICTOR
BLACKWELL IN ATLANTA FOR THE
LATEST ON SOME OF THE OTHER
STORIES MAKING HEADLINES TODAY.
>>> THANK YOU.
IN WASHINGTON WE COULD BE A STEP
CLOSER TO A DEAL THAT WOULD
PREVENT THE U.S. FROM FALLING
OFF THAT FISCAL CLIFF.
SOURCES TELL CNN THAT SPEAKER
JOHN BOEHNER IS PREPARED TO
RAISE TAXES ON THE WEALTHY,
SPECIFICALLY THOSE MAKING $1
MILLION OR MORE AS PART OF A
PLAN TO REDUCE DEFICITS.
TAX HIKES FOR THE WEALTHY ARE
SOMETHING THE PRESIDENT SAID
MUST BE INCLUDED IN EVERY PLAN.
IT'S A CHANGE FROM BOEHNER'S
PREVIOUS POSITION.
HE CALLED ANY TAX INCREASES A
NONSTARTER.
STAYING IN WASHINGTON, PRESIDENT
OBAMA APPEARS SET TO NOMINATE
SENATOR JOHN KERRY AS HIS NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE.
THE FORMAL ANNOUNCEMENT COULD
COME THIS WEEK.
SUSAN RICE WAS THE EXPECTED
CHOICE, BUT SHE PULLED HER NAME
OUT OF THE RUNNING BECAUSE OF
THE CONTROVERSY OVER HER
COMMENTS IN THE WAKE OF BENGHAZI
ATTACKS.
HILLARY CLINTON WAS SUPPOSED IT
TO TESTIFY THIS WEEK, BUT
STHAETS ON HOLD.
SHE SUFFERED A CONCUSSION AND IS
RESTING AT HOME.
SHE BATTLED A STOMACH VIRUS AND
FAINTED AFTER BEING DEHYDRATED,
BUT HER OFFICE SAYS IT'S NOT
SEVERE.
>>> ALL OF OUR HEARTS ARE HEAVY
THIS WEEKEND WITH THE TRAGIC
STORY OUT OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, BUT COMING UP, A
REMINDER WE COULD ALL USE.
THAT GOOD THINGS DO STILL
HAPPEN.
SO, THIS BOARD
GIVES ME RATES FOR
PROGRESSIVE DIRECT AND OTHER
CAR INSURANCE COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
CALL OR CLICK TODAY.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.