SOMETHING THAT DEFINES US, BUT
SOMETHING THAT INSPIRES US TO BE
BETTER, TO BE MORE COMPASSIONATE
AND MORE HUMBLE PEOPLE.
>> A FATHER, A FAMILY, A
COMMUNITY IN GRIEF.
THEIR HEARTS ARE HEAVY.
WEARY OF THESE TRAGEDIES.
I'M DON LEMON.
>>> GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE.
I'M JOHN BERMAN.
>> I'M KATE BOLDUAN.
WE'RE LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL BE
COMING HERE LATER TODAY.
HE WILL MEET WITH SOME OF THE
VICTIMS' FAMILIES AND SPEAK AT A
VIGIL BEING HELD HERE TONIGHT.
MEANWHILE, WE'RE LEARNING MORE
ABOUT THIS TRAGEDY AND THE
VICTIMS, 20 CHILDREN, 6 ADULTS
DIED IN FRIDAY'S SHOOTING AT THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> EVERYBODY'S DEATH WAS CAUSED
BY, EVERYONE THAT WE COMPLETED
SO FAR WAS CAUSED BY GUNSHOT
WOUNDS.
AND, OBVIOUSLY, THE MANNER OF
DEATH ON ALL THESE CASES HAS
BEEN CLASSIFIED AS HOMICIDE.
>> THAT WAS THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER.
HE ALSO OFFERED THIS DISTURBING
DETAIL.
ALL OF THE VICTIMS HE'S SEEN,
THEY WERE SHOT MORE THAN ONCE.
>> JUST AMAZING TO EVEN HEAR HIM
RECOUNT WHAT HE'S SEEN IN REALLY
CHILLING, CHILLY DETAIL, TOM.
>> WE WILL HAVE MUCH MORE ON THE
VICTIMS.
OF COURSE, THEIR NAMES AND THEIR
STORIES COMING UP IN JUST A FEW
MINUTES.
PEOPLE IN THIS COMMUNITY ARE
STILL COMING TO GRIPS WITH THIS
TRAGEDY.
UNDERSTANDABLY, WE SAW MORE
VIGILS HERE LAST NIGHT AND
THEY'RE STILL OFFERING GRIEF
COUNSELING TO MANY.
THAT'S ESPECIALLY IMPORTANT FOR
THE KIDS WHO LOST SO MANY OF
THEIR FRIENDS IN THIS SHOOTING.
WE ALSO WANT TO PASS THIS ALONG
TO YOU.
THE UNITED WAY HAS SET UP A
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL FUND.
DONATIONS CAN BE SENT TO THE
NEWTOWN SAVINGS BANK.
THE ADDRESS YOU SEE ON YOUR
SCREEN, NEWTOWN SAVINGS BANK, 39
MAIN STREET, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, 06470.
WE ARE ALSO HEARING FROM ADAM
LANZA'S FAMILY.
BOTH HIS BROTHER, RYAN, AND HIS
FATHER HAVE BEEN QUESTIONED BY
POLICE.
PETER LANZA RELEASED THIS
STATEMENT.
"OUR FAMILY IS GRIEVING ALONG
WITH ALL THOSE WHO HAVE BEEN
AFFECTED BY THIS ENORMOUS
TRAGEDY.
WE ARE IN A STATE OF DISBELIEF
AND TRYING TO FIND WHATEVER
ANSWERS WE CAN.
WE TOO, ARE ASKING WHY."
WE'RE HEARING FROM ADAM LANZA'S
AUNT WHICH SAYS SHE'S SHOCKED
AND OFFERS A LITTLE INSIGHT INTO
WHY.
>> I KNOW SHE HAD ISSUES WITH
SCHOOL.
SHE WOUND UP HOMESCHOOLING HIM,
BECAUSE SHE BATTLED WITH THE
SCHOOL DISTRICT I'M NOT SURE IN
WHAT CAPACITY.
>> HAS HE ACTED OUT?
HAD SHE SHARED WITH YOU?
>> NO.
>> NO VIOLENCE TOWARDS HER?
IF HE DID, I KNOW SHE WOULDN'T
HAVE TOLERATED IT.
>> JOINING US NOW NATIONAL
CORRESPONDENT SUSAN CANDIOTTI.
YOU HAVE BEEN FOLLOWING THIS
INVESTIGATION FROM THE VERY,
VERY BEGINNING.
WHAT MORE ARE WE LEARNING ABOUT
ADAM LANZA AND WHAT HE WAS DOING
IN THE DAYS BEFORE THE SHOOTING?
>> OF COURSE, THAT'S ONE OF THE
MANY KEY QUESTIONS THAT
AUTHORITIES ARE TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT.
AS WE'RE BEGINNING TO SEE MORE
PHOTOGRAPHS EMERGE OF THIS
20-YEAR-OLD YOUNG MAN, OF
COURSE, THE PHOTOS WE'VE SEEN OF
HIM ARE AT A VERY MUCH YOUNGER
AGE.
DP
AGAIN, HE WAS ONLY 20, BUT A LOT
OF THE PHOTOS WERE TAKEN WHEN HE
WAS JUST A TEENAGER.
INVESTIGATORS HAVE BEEN CHASING
DOWN A LOT OF LEADS IN THIS
AREA.
THEY HAVE BEEN TALKING TO
FRIENDS AND FAMILY AND NEIGHBORS
TO TRY TO LEARN MORE ABOUT HIM
AS AN INDIVIDUAL AND, AGAIN,
WHERE HE WAS IN THE DAYS BEFORE
THE SHOOTING.
SO, FOR EXAMPLE, THEY HAVE BEEN
SPENDING A LOT OF TIME, JOHN AND
KATE, AT VARIOUS GUN RANGES AND
GUN SHOPS IN THE AREA.
AGAIN, CHASING DOWN INFORMATION
THAT HE MAY HAVE VISITED SOME OF
THESE PLACES.
AND ONE OF THE STOPS TOOK THEM
TO A LOCAL SPORTING GOODS STORE.
IT'S A CHAIN AND IT'S LOCATED IN
DANBURY, CONNECTICUT.
SOMEONE MAY HAVE PURCHASED A GUN
THERE, POSSIBLY HIM ON TUESDAY,
BUT DECIDED AGAINST IT.
THEY SPENT A LOT OF TIME THERE
TALKING TO EMPLOYEES AND EVEN
TRACKING DOWN THE STORE'S
SURVEILLANCE CAMERA VIDEOS TO
SEE IF THEY CAN CAPTURE HIM ON
TAPE, BUT THAT TIP DID NOT PAN
OUT.
WE UNDERSTAND THAT AUTHORITIES
HAVE PLANS TO KEEP DOING THAT
TODAY.
JOHN?
>> AND, SUSAN, ARE WE GETTING
ANY SENSE OF ANY NEW INFORMATION
OF REALLY WHAT TRANSPIRED AT THE
SCHOOL FRIDAY MORNING AND THE
IMPOSSIBLE QUESTION IS REALLY,
IS THERE ANY EVIDENCE YET
POINTING TOWARDS A MOTIVE?
>> OH, THE MOTIVE, NO.
WE'VE BEEN ASKING THAT, AGAIN
AND AGAIN.
WE DID HEAR FROM INVESTIGATORS
SAYING THAT THEY ARE PICKING UP
WHAT THEY CALL VERY IMPORTANT
EVIDENCE TO TRY TO FIGURE THAT
OUT AT BOTH THE CRIME SCENE AND
AT THE HOME THAT THE SHOOTER
SHARED WITH HIS MOTHER.
BUT THEY'RE NOT REVEALING WHAT
THEY CONSIDER TO BE THAT
IMPORTANT EVIDENCE.
WE DO KNOW THIS, THAT THE THREE
GUNS THAT HE TOOK THERE, GUNS
THAT WERE LEGALLY PURCHASED,
ACCORDING TO AUTHORITIES BY HIS
MOTHER, THOSE THREE GUNS WERE
FOUND NEXT TO HIS BODY,
INCLUDING ONE THAT HE KILLED
HIMSELF WITH.
THEY KNOW WHICH ONE THAT WAS,
BUT THEY'RE NOT SAYING.
REMEMBER, HE TOOK WITH HIM TWO
HANDGUNS AND A LONG GUN CALLED A
BUSHMASTER.
WE KNOW FROM THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER THAT HE USED THAT LONG
GUN TO KILL A NUMBER OF HIS
VICTIMS, AS YOU INDICATED
EARLIER, KATE, WE KNOW THAT HE
SHOT MANY OF THIZ VICTIMS
SEVERAL TIMES, ACCORDING TO THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER, ANYWHERE FROM
3 TO 11 TIMES EACH.
JUST A VICIOUS, COLD BLOODED
EVENT THAT AUTHORITIES HAVE
CALLED BEING BLAMED ON SOMEONE
WHO WAS VERY, VERY EVIL AND WE
CAN UNDERSTAND WHY.
KATE?
>> YEAH.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI DOING GREAT
REPORTING ON THIS VERY, VERY
DIFFICULT STORY.
SUSAN, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>>> FOR MORE INFORMATION ON HOW
YOU CAN HELP THOSE AFFECTED, SO
MANY PEOPLE ARE ASKING HOW,
WELL, YOU CAN HELP THOSE
AFFECTED BY THE SHOOTING, YOU
CAN GO TO CNN.COM/IMPACT.
YOU CAN ALSO OFFER YOUR THANKS
AND IMPACT YOUR WORLD, AS WE
LIKE TO SAY, JOHN.
>>> BRING IN VICTOR BLACKWELL IN
ATLANTA WHO IS MONITORING SOME
OF THE OTHER STORIES FOR US.
>> HERE ARE SOME OF THE OTHER
THINGS HAPPENING AROUND THE
WORLD.
16 DAYS BEFORE THE U.S. CAN GO
OVER THE FISCAL CLIFF, A DEAL
MIGHT BE NEAR.
A SOURCE CLOSE TO THE TALKS TELL
CNN THAT HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER IS WILLING TO HIKE TAXES
ON THE WEALTHIEST AMERICANS.
THAT'S SOMETHING THE PRESIDENT
SAYS MUST BE INCLUDED IN ANY
PLAN.
BOEHNER PREVIOUSLY CALLED TAX
INCREASES ON EARNERS A
NONSTARTER.
HE AND THE PRESIDENT HAVE NOT
REACHED A DEAL.
>>> STAYING IN WASHINGTON,
PRESIDENT OBAMA APPEARS SET TO
NOMINATE SENATOR JOHN KERRY AS
HIS NEXT SECRETARY OF STATE.
HILLARY CLINTON SAID SHE WOULD
STEP DOWN AFTER THE FIRST TERM.
SUSAN RICE WAS THE EXPECTED
CHOICE, BUT SHE PULLED HER NAME
OUT OF THE RUNNING BECAUSE OF
THE CONTROVERSY OVER HER
COMMENTS IN THE WAKE OF THE
BENGHAZI ATTACKS.
>>> SECRETARY CLINTON WAS
SUPPOSED TO TESTIFY ABOUT
BENGHAZI THIS WEEK, BUT THAT'S
ON HOLD NOW.
SHE SUFFERED A CONCUSSION AND
NOW SHE'S RESTING AT HOME.
THE SECRETARY HAS BEEN BATTLING
A STOMACH VIRUS AND FAINTED
AFTER BECOMING DEHYDRATED.
HER OFFICE SAYS IT'S NOT SEVERE.
>>> IT'S ELECTION DAY IN JAPAN
AND VOTERS ARE CHOOSING A NEW
PARLIAMENT.
THE ELECTION COULD RETURN FORMER
PRIME MINISTER TO OFFICE IF HIS
LIBERAL DEMOCRATIC PARTY WINS
AND LOTS OF ANALYSTS EXPECT THAT
HE'LL WIN BIG.
HE'S PROMISED TO GET JAPAN'S
STRUGGLING ECONOMY BACK ON
TRACK.
LET'S GO BACK NOW TO KATE
BOLDUAN AND JOHN BERMAN IN
CONNECTICUT.
>> THERE ARE NEWS GOING ON
AROUND THE WORLD AND THANK YOU,
VICTOR, FOR KEEPING US TO SPEED
ON THAT.
>>> PEOPLE WILL BE GOING TO
CHURCH SERVICES THIS MORNING TO
GRIEVE FOR THEIR LOVED ONES.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> WE'LL TELL YOU SOME
INCREDIBLE AND HEARTWARMING
STORIES ABOUT THE VICTIMS, BUT,
FIRST, WE WANT TO SHOW YOU THE
NAMES AND THE AGES OF ALL 26
PEOPLE KILLED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL ON THAT FRIDAY
MORNING TO HONOR THEIR PASSING.
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
HOW THEY'LL LIVE TOMORROW.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN DIARRHEA HITS,
KAOPECTATE STOPS IT FAST.
POWERFUL LIQUID RELIEF
SPEEDS TO THE SOURCE.
FAST.
[ Male Announcer ]
STOP THE UH-OH FAST
WITH KAOPECTATE.
>>> IN A FEW HOURS, PEOPLE HERE
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WILL
HEAD TO CHURCH SERVICES TO SEEK
COMFORT AND MOURN THE LOSS OF SO
MANY OF THEIR LOVED ONES.
THEIR FRIENDS, FAMILY MEMBERS
AND MANY PEOPLE THEY HAVE KNOWN
FOR SO MANY YEARS.
WE NOW KNOW 12 GIRLS AND 8 BOYS
WERE SHOT TO DEATH INSIDE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
ALL OF THEM WERE EITHER 6 OR 7
YEARS OLD.
AMONG THEM, WAS EMILY PARKER.
HER FATHER SAYS SHE COULD LIGHT
UP A ROOM AND WAS AN EXCEPTIONAL
ARTIST WHO ALWAYS CARRIED AROUND
MARKERS AND PENCILS TO DRAW FOR
ANYONE.
HER DAD SAID HE DWAV HER A KISS
THE LAST TIME HE SAW HER ALIVE.
SIX ADULTS LOST THEIR LIVES IN
THAT TRAGIC SHOOTING.
THAT INCLUDES 47-YEAR-OLD
PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG WHO
WAS MARRIED AND HAD TWO
DAUGHTERS AND THREE ST
STEPDAUGHTERS.
ONE PARENT SAID HOCHSPRUNG WAS
ALWAYS SMILING.
AND SCHOOL SIPSYCHOLOGIST MARY
SHERLACH LOVED TO GARDEN.
THEY WILL MISS HER TERRIBLY AND
TAKE COMFORT KNOWING SHE HAD
ACHIEVED THAT DREAM.
THE GUNMAN ALSO TOOK THE LIFE OF
A 27-YEAR-OLD FIRST GRADE
TEACHER WHO IS BEING HAILED
AROUND THE WORLD FOR HER
BRAVERY.
♪ AMAZING GRACE
HOW SWEET THE SOUND ♪
>> HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE SANG
"AMAZING GRACE" AT A CANDLELIGHT
VIGIL FOR VICTORIA SOTO IN HER
HOMETOWN.
SHE MOVED HER STUDENTS FROM THE
CLASSROOM DOOR WHEN THEY HEARD
THE GUN SHOTS RINGING OUT.
SHE FACED THE GUNMAN WHEN HE
STORMED IN AND HE SHOT HER.
I SPOKE YESTERDAY WITH TWO
PARENTS WHOSE SON, BY WHAT THEY
CALL A MIRACLE, MADE IT OUT OF
THAT CLASSROOM ALIVE.
>> WHEN THEY HEARD NOISES THAT
HE DESCRIBED INITIALLY THEY
THOUGHT WERE HAMMERS FALLING,
THEN THEY REALIZED THAT IT WAS
G
GUNSHOTS AND MS. SOTO, WHO WAS
A
AIDEN'S TEACHER HAD THE
KNOWLEDGE TO MOVE THE CHILDREN
AWAY FROM THE DOOR AND THAT'S
WHEN THE GUNMAN BURST IN, DID
NOT SAY A WORD, NO FACIAL
EXPRESSIONS AND PROCEEDED TO
SHOOT THEIR TEACHER.
AND THEY BASICALLY RAN RIGHT
NEXT TO THE GUY AND OUT THE
DOOR.
>> THEY RAN PAST HIM?
>> HE'S STILL STANDING IN THE
DOOR AND THEY RAN PAST HIM AND
RAN DOWN THE HALLWAY AND THEY'RE
ONE OF THE CLOSEST ROOMS TO THE
MAIN ENTRANCE AND AIDEN WAS, HAD
THE PRESENCE OF MIND TO HOLD THE
DOOR FOR ONE OF HIS CLASSMATES
AND THEN ANOTHER ONE OF HIS
CLASSMATES THAT WAS A LITTLE
BEHIND AND WAITED FOR HIM AND
THEN THEY ALL RAN TO THE ROAD,
TO THE MAIN ROAD.
>> DO YOU THINK HE KNOWS SHE
DIDN'T MAKE IT?
>> HE'S REASSURING HIMSELF THAT
SHE'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
HE REALLY, REALLY, REALLY A
CARED ABOUT HIS TEACHER.
HE WAS VERY CLOSE WITH HER AND
SHE REALLY LOVED THEIR CLASS.
HE KEPT SAYING THAT I HOPE SHE'S
OKAY.
I HOPE IT'S NOT HER.
HE KNOWS THAT SHE'S BEEN HURT,
BUT HE DOESN'T KNOW THE END
RESULT.
HE KNOWS THE KIDS THAT HE SAW
GETTING SHOT.
HE DOESN'T KNOW THE OUTCOME.
SO, I THINK HE'S REASSURING
HIMSELF IN HIS 6-YEAR-OLD MIND.
I KNOW HE'S PROCESSING IT, BUT I
THINK HE'S REASSURING HIMSELF.
I THINK HE'S TELLING HIMSELF
THAT IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
WE HAD TO PUT THE SIGN OUT IN
THE FRONT TODAY ASKING PEOPLE
NOT TO RING THE DOORBELL BECAUSE
HE STILL HASN'T INTERNALIZED THE
FACT THAT THIS GUNMAN, THIS BAD
GUY IS GONE AND HE WANTS TO KNOW
IF THERE ARE MORE BAD GUYS IN
THE WORLD AND I DON'T KNOW HOW
TO ANSWER THAT QUESTION
PROPERLY.
AND, SO, WHEN SOMEONE RINGS THE
DOORBELL, HE THINKS IT'S HIM
COMING BACK, COMING FOR HIM.
SO, HE, YOU KNOW, HE -- SO, I
THINK OUR BIGGEST CONCERN NOW IS
MAKING SURE THAT WE HANDLE HIS
SENSITIVE NATURE PROPERLY AND
CAREFULLY AND SUPPORT HIM AND
SUPPORT OUR DAUGHTER BECAUSE
SHE, AGAIN, DOES PROCESS THINGS
VERY DIFFERENTLY THAN HE DOES.
THAT'S OUR JOB AS PARENTS NOW TO
STAY CLOSE TO THEM, HOLD THEM,
HUG THEM, LOVE THEM AND LET THEM
KNOW THAT THEY ARE SAFE.
>> THAT WAS ROBERT AND DIANE
LACATA.
THEY WERE WONDERFUL TO SIT DOWN
AND TALK TO US.
WE WANT TO SAY THAT VICTORIA
SOTO'S COUSIN, HER PARENTS AND
FAMILY MEMBERS SAY THEY ARE VERY
PROUD THAT SHE HAD THE INSTINCT
TO PROTECT HER STUDENTS AND
THAT, AND THAT THAT BRINGS THEM
SOME PEACE ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED.
THEY, OF COURSE, SAY, SHE IS A
HERO.
IT WAS PRETTY SPECIAL FOR MEAD
TO SPEND SOME TIME WITH THEM.
>> WE'RE BEING SO SENSITIVE TO
THE PEOPLE HERE IN THIS
COMMUNITY.
WE'RE NOT BARGING IN AND PUTTING
MICROPHONES IN AND WE ARE ONLY
TALKING TO PEOPLE WHO INVITE US
IN.
YOU GOT TO SPEND TIME WITH THAT
6-YEAR-OLD AIDEN.
>> HIS PARENTS DID NOT WANT HIM
TO BE PART OF THE INTERVIEW,
WHICH IS UNDERSTANDABLE.
HE'S STILL TRYING TO DEAL WITH
THIS TRAGEDY AND THEY DON'T KNOW
EXACTLY YET HOW TO HELP THIM
THROUGH IT.
THEY KNOW THEY WANT TO LET HIM
LEAD THE WAY IN HOW HE'S DEALING
WITH THE TRAGEDY.
HE WAS IN VERY HIGH SPIRITS.
HE WAS A 6-YEAR-OLD BOY, HE WAS
SHOWING ME HIS KONG FU MOVES.
HIS SISTER IS A SECOND GRADER AT
SANDY HOOK.
I SPENT TIME WITH THE SISTER
YESTERDAY, AS WELL.
THEY ARE ABSOLUTELY ADORABLE,
PRECIOUS AND DRIVE HOME THE
PRECIOUS LITTLE LIVES THAT WERE
IN THOSE CLASSROOMS AND WHAT WAS
LOST.
THESE TWO PARENT SAY THEY'RE SO
LUCKY TO BE ABLE TO BE HUGGING
THEIR CHILDREN.
>> AMAZING RESILIENCE FOR
AMAZING KIDS.
>>> OUR COVERAGE OF THIS TRAGEDY
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WILL
CONTINUE IN JUST A MOMENT.
[ Female Announcer ] BORN FROM
THE NATURALLY SWEET MONK FRUIT,
SOMETHING THIS DELICIOUS
COULD ONLY COME FROM NATURE.
NOW FROM THE MAKER
OF SPLENDA SWEETENERS,
DISCOVER NECTRESSE.
THE ONLY 100% NATURAL,
NO-CALORIE SWEETENER
MADE FROM THE GOODNESS
OF FRUIT.
THE RICH, SWEET TASTE OF SUGAR.
NOTHING ARTIFICIAL.
♪
IT'S ALL THAT SWEET
EVER NEEDS TO BE.
NEW NECTRESSE.
SWEETNESS NATURALLY.
>>> VIGILS, PRAYERS, WORDS OF
REFLECTION.
THE NATION IS REMEMBERING THE
VICTIMS OF THE SCHOOL SHOOTING
HERE IN CONNECTICUT IN THEIR OWN
WAY.
THIS IS HOW "SATURDAY NIGHT
LIVE" PAID TRIBUTE.
♪ SILENT NIGHT
HOLY NIGHT ♪
♪ ALL IS CALM
ALL IS BRIGHT ♪
>> THAT IS SIMPLY BEAUTIFUL.
THE SKETCH COMEDY SHOW OPENED
THIS WEEKEND SHOW WITH A CHORUS
OF CHILDREN SINGING THE CLASSIC
CHRISTMAS SONG "SILENT NIGHT."
>>> IN MIAMI, THE MIAMI HEAT
PLAYERS STOOD WITH THEIR
CHILDREN FOR A MOMENT OF SILENCE
BEFORE SATURDAY'S GAME AGAINST
THE WASHINGTON WIZARDS.
THEY WANTED TO PAY RESPECT TO
THE SHOOTING VICTIMS.
THE NEW ENGLAND PATRIOTS AS FAR
AWAY AS ENGLAND SOCCER PLAYERS
WERE WEARING ON THEIR UNIFORM TO
MOURN WITH THE PEOPLE HERE IN
CONNECTICUT.
CLEARLY THE SHOCKWAVES FROM THIS
SENSELESS MASSACRE THAT LEFT 20
CHILDREN AND 6 ADULTS DEAD ARE
BEING FELT FAR, FAR BEYOND OUR
BORDERS.
FOR MORE NOW ON THE TRULY GLOBAL
REACTION TO THIS, I WANT TO
BRING IN VICTOR BLACKWELL.
WHAT HAVE YOU SEEN HOW THE WORLD
IS REACTING HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> YOU MENTIONED THE SOCCER
PLAYERS IN THE UK AND WE'RE
GETTING RESPONSE FROM THE UK AND
ALL OVER THE WORLD.
IF THERE IS ONE THING ASIDE FROM
POLITICAL DISAGREEMENTS THAT THE
WORLD CAN AGREE ON IS THE
INNOCENCE OF OUR CHILDREN,
SPECIFICALLY, FROM DAVID
CAMERON, THE BRITISH PRIME
MINISTER, YOU KNOW, BACK IN
1996, THEY SUFFERED THROUGH A
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
HIS STAMENTD FROM TEN DOWNING.
MY THOUGHTS ARE WITH THE INJURED
AND THOSE WHO HAVE LOST LOVED
ONES.
IT IS HEARTBREAKING TO THINK OF
THOSE WHO HAVE HAD THEIR
CHILDREN ROBBED FROM THEM AT
SUCH A YOUNG AGE WHEN THEY HAD
SO MUCH LIFE AHEAD OF THEM.
AS WE MENTIED THAT SHOOTING IN
'96 AND ALSO IN '96 A SHOOTING
IN TASMANIA THAT ENDED WITH FIVE
PEOPLE BEING KILLED.
THAT STATEMENT AFTER THAT WE
RECEIVED FROM PRIME MINISTER
JULIE GILLARD.
>> IT IS ALMOST BEYOND
COMPREHENSION, BUT THAT IS WHAT
WE HAVE SEEN TODAY.
HEARTFELT SYMPATHIES GO TO THOSE
FAMILIES WHO HAVE LOST A CHILD.
TO THOSE FAMILIES WHO HAVE LOST
A LOVED ONE.
TO THOSE FAMILIES WHO ARE NOW
TRYING TO COUNSEL THEIR YOUNG
CHILDREN THAT HAS BEEN WITNESS
TO SUCH SHOCKING SCENES AND SO
DISTRESSED AS A RESULT.
>> TWO OF THE STATEMENTS FROM
COMING ALL ACROSS THE WORLD IN
DEMONSTRATIONS OF SOLIDARITY.
BACK TO YOU, JOHN, IN NEWTOWN.
>> VICTOR, YOU SAID IT SO WELL.
IF THERE IS ONE THING THAT IS
UNIVERSAL, IT IS THE LOVE FOR
OUR CHILDREN.
VICTOR BLACKWELL IN ATLANTA,
WE'LL COME BACK TO YOU IN A
LITTLE BIT.
FOR MORE INFORMATION ON HOW YOU
CAN HELP THOSE AFFECTED BY THE
SHOOTING GO TO CNN.COM/IMPACT.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
PROGRESSIVE DIRECT AND OTHER
CAR INSURANCE COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
CALL OR CLICK TODAY.
>>> HERE'S A LOOK AT THIS WEEK'S
MORTGAGE RATES.
CHECK OUT
MY NEW TREADMILL APP.
PRETTY SWEET, HUH?
CUTE.
BUT DON'T YOU HAVE ANY APPS
ON YOUR PHONE
THAT CAN MAKE YOUR LIFE
EASIER?
WHO DO YOU THINK I AM,
Quicken Loans?
AT Quicken Loans, WE'LL PROVIDE
YOU WITH MYQL MOBILE.
THIS AMAZINGLY USEFUL APP
ALLOWS YOU
TO TAKE PICTURES
OF YOUR MORTGAGE DOCUMENTS
USING AN iPhone
OR Android SMART PHONE...
SO YOU CAN EASILY
SEND THEM TO US.
ONE MORE WAY Quicken Loans
IS Engineered to Amaze.
OOH, LA-LA!
Neural speeds
increasing to 4G LTE.
Brain upgrading to a quad-core
processor.
Predictive intelligence
with Google Now complete.
Introducing DROID DNA by HTC.
It's not an upgrade
to your phone.
It's an upgrade to yourself.
>>> WELCOME, ONCE AGAIN.
WE ARE CONTINUING OUR VERY
SPECIAL COVERAGE OF THE SANDY
HOOK SHOOTING.
THIS MORNING LIVE FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
IT IS HALF PAST THE HOUR, THANK
YOU SO MUCH FOR JOINING US THIS
MORNING.
HERE IN NEWTOWN, PEOPLE ARE
STILL ASKING WHY AND HOW.
QUESTIONS THAT WE MAY NOT HAVE
ANSWERS FOR FOR A VERY LONG
TIME, IF AT ALL.
THEY ARE ALSO REMEMBERING THE
VICTIMS.
WE SAW MORE VIGILS HERE LAST
NIGHT, AS PEOPLE PAY THEIR
RESPECTS TO THE 20 CHILDREN AND
6 ADULTS KILLED IN THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
ALL OF THOSE CHILDREN WERE JUST
6 OR 7 YEARS OLD.
INVESTIGATORS ARE STILL TRYING
TO PIECE IT ALTOGETHER.
THEY FOUND MORE INFORMATION ON
THE SHOOTER, BUT, STILL, NO
MOTIVE.
CNN NATIONAL CORRESPONDENT SUSAN
CANDIOTTI HAS BEEN FOLLOWING THE
INVESTIGATION FROM THE VERY
BEGINNING.
SUSAN, WHAT MORE DO YOU KNOW?
WELL, GOOD MORNING, KATE.
WE KNOW THAT INVESTIGATORS TELL
US THAT THEY ARE MAKING
PROGRESS, BUT THEY'RE NOT SAYING
EXACTLY WHAT KIND OF PROGRESS
THEY'RE MAKING.
WE KNOW, FOR EXAMPLE, THEY HAVE
BEEN TALKING TO FAMILY AND
FRIENDS OF THE SHOOTER ADAM
LANZA TO TRY TO DEVELOP A
PROFILE ABOUT WHAT HE WAS ALL
ABOUT.
FOR EXAMPLE, THEY ARE VERY
INTERESTED IN ANYTHING HE MAY
HAVE WRITTEN DOWN.
ANY E-MAILS HE MAY HAVE SENT AS
THEY TRY TO PIECE TOGETHER SOME
KIND OF A MOTIVE AND WHAT HE WAS
DOING IN THE DAYS BEFORE THE
SHOOTING.
INVESTIGATORS ARE LEARNING MORE
EACH DAY THAT MAY EXPLAIN WHAT
LED 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA TO
LAUNCH A VICIOUS ATTACK ON YOUNG
CHILDREN AND ADULTS AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> OUR INVESTIGATORS AT THE
CRIME SCENE, THE SCHOOL AND
SECONDARY AT THE SECOND CRIME
SCENE WE DISCUSSED DID PRODUCE
SOME VERY, VERY GOOD EVIDENCE IN
THIS INVESTIGATION THAT OUR
INVESTIGATORS WILL BE ABLE TO
USE AND HOPEFULLY PAINTING THE
COMPLETE PICTURE AS TO HOW AND,
MORE IMPORTANTLY, WHY THIS
OCCURRED.
>> Reporter: POLICE WON'T SAY
WHAT THAT EVIDENCE IS, HOWEVER,
INVESTIGATORS HAVE BEEN CHECKING
OUT GUN RANGES AND SPORTING GOOD
STORES.
THEY FOLLOWED A LEAD THE SHOOTER
TRIED TO BUY A GUN TUESDAY AT
THIS LOCATION.
AFTER SEARCHING STORE
SURVEILLANCE VIDEOS, THE TIP
DIDN'T PAN OUT.
>> TO DATE, ATF HAVE NOT
UNCOVERED ANY INFORMATION TO
SUBSTANTIATE THE FACT THAT HE
TRIED TO ACQUIRE GUNS RECENTLY.
WE'RE OUT THERE ACTIVELY
INVESTIGATING.
>> Reporter: FEDERAL GUN AGENTS
SAID THEY ALSO RECOVERED WEAPONS
AT THE HOME THE SHOOTER SHARE
WOULD HIS MOTHER.
SOURCES SAY THREE MORE GUNS WERE
FOUND.
THESE THREE RIFLE MODELS, ALL
OLDER.
THEY'RE BEING TRACED, AT LEAST
ONE, HAS BEEN CONNECTED TO THE
MOTHER.
THREE MORE WEAPONS WERE
DISCOVERED WITH THE SHOOTER IN A
CLASSROOM, WHERE HE TOOK HIS OWN
LIFE.
ACCORDING TO LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS, THE TWO HANDGUNS AND
SEMI-AUTOMATIC BUSHMASTER WERE
BOUGHT LEGALLY BY HIS MOTHER.
THAT LONG GUN WAS USED TO KILL
SEVERAL VICTIMS.
>> I ONLY DID SEVEN OF THE
AUTOPSIES.
THE VICTIMS RANGED FROM 3 TO 11
WOUNDS EACH.
ALL THE WOUNDS I KNOW OF AT THIS
POINT WERE ALL CAUSED BY THE
LONG WEAPON.
>> ONE MAN WHO SAID THAT HE KNEW
OF THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER
DESCRIBED HER AS A GUN
ENTHUSIAST WHO LIKED TO TAKE HER
SONS TARGET SHOOTING.
BUT SO FAR AUTHORITIES SAY THEY
HAVE FOUND NO EVIDENCE OF THAT.
RELATIVES DESCRIBE HIM AS A
BRIGHT YOUNG MAN WHO WAS
HOMESCHOOLED.
HIS BROTHER, ACCORDING TO LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS TOLD
INVESTIGATORS THAT THE YOUNGER
BROTHER, THE SHOOTER, WAS
AUTISTIC, BUT CERTAINLY NONE OF
THIS ADDS UP FOR INVESTIGATORS
SO FAR.
WHY HE ALLEGEDLY DID WHAT HE
DID.
KATE?
>> SUSAN, YOU HEARD IN THE PIECE
LIEUTENANT VANCE SAY THEY DID
RECOVER MATERIALS AT THE HOUSE
THAT WILL BE KEY IN HELPING TO
TELL THE STORY OF WHAT MAY HAVE
CAUSED THIS TO HAPPEN.
WHAT LED UP TO IT.
DO YOU HAVE ANY SENSE OF WHAT
TYPES OF MATERIALS THOSE MIGHT
BE?
>> THEY'RE SIMPLY NOT SAYING.
SO, WE'VE CERTAINLY PRESSED THEM
ON IT.
DOES THAT MEAN THAT THEY'VE BEEN
LOOKING AT A COMPUTER AND
LOOKING AT LETTERS OR WRITTEN OR
ANY KIND OF LETTERS HE MIGHT
HAVE WRITTEN DOWN TO PEOPLE TO
TRY TO EXPRESS HIS THOUGHTS.
BUT THEY'RE NOT SAYING EXACTLY
WHAT THAT WAS.
DID SOMETHING HAVE TO DO WITH
THE GUN COLLECTION THAT THE
MOTHER HAD THERE?
IT CERTAINLY APPEARS, JOHN, AS
YOU KNOW, HE APPEARED TO HAVE
USED ONE OF THOSE GUNS TO KILL
HIS OWN MOTHER.
>> AND, SUSAN, ALSO YOU HAD SAID
EARLIER THIS HOUR THAT IT
APPEARS THAT INVESTIGATORS KNOW
WHICH WEAPON THIS YOUNG, THIS
YOUNG MAN USED ON HIMSELF, BUT
ARE STILL WITHHOLDING THAT
INFORMATION.
WHAT'S THE PROCESS OF THIS?
WHY WITHHOLD THE INFORMATION?
THESE INVESTIGATORS HAVEN'T
REALLY COME OUT PUBLICLY YET TO
EVEN I.D. HIM.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
THAT'S AN IMPORTANT POINT WE'VE
BEEN ASKING THAT TIME AND AGAIN.
BUT, WE KEEP HEARING, LOOK, THIS
IS A DECISION BEING MADE BY THE
LEAD INVESTIGATORS OF THIS CASE,
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE AND
THEY HAVE CHOSEN NOT TO FORMALLY
RELEASE THE NAME OF THE SHOOTER
AT THIS TIME.
WE STILL DON'T HAVE AN
EXPLANATION, FOR EXAMPLE, AS TO
WHY THERE WAS A MIX UP ON THE
DAY THAT THIS HAPPENED.
WHEN INITIALLY SOURCES AND LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS WERE
IDENTIFYING THE SHOOTER AS THE
OLDER BROTHER WHEN, IN FACT, IT
WAS THE YOUNGER BROTHER.
WE STILL DON'T KNOW WHAT
HAPPENED THERE EITHER.
>> YEAH.
ABSOLUTELY.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI, GREAT REPORTING
FOR YOU HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THANKS SO MUCH.
>> EVERY HOUR THAT DOES PASHERE
WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE
TRAGIC DEATHS OF THE 26 PEOPLE
AT THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
OFFICIALS SAY THE VICTIMS WERE
SHOT MULTIPLE TIMES AND THAT
MOST WERE KILLED BY THIS RIFLE.
WE KNOW THE .223 CALIBER
BUSHMASTER SEMI-AUTOMATIC WAS
FOUND NEAR THE SHOOTER WHEN HE
WAS DECEASED AND LEGALLY
PURCHASED BY NANCY LANZA, THE
SHOOTER'S MOTHER.
TOM FUENTES, ALSO A CNN
CONTRIBUTOR.
TOM, KNOWING NOW THAT THIS
BUSHMASTER, THIS ASSAULT WEAPON
WAS THE LIKELY GUN THAT WAS
USED.
ARE YOU EVEN SURPRISED THE
SITUATION WASN'T WORSE?
>> WELL, IT WOULD BE PRETTY
HORRIFIC JUST BECAUSE OF THAT,
JOHN.
THE BUSHMASTER BULLET WOULD BE
ABOUT THREE TIMES FASTER, LONGER
AND MORE POWERFUL THAN THE
BULLETS THAT WOULD HAVE BEEN
FIRED FROM THE TWO HANDGUNS.
SO, I THINK THAT WHEN THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER YESTERDAY
MENTIONED THAT ALL OF THE WOUNDS
ALL OF THE VICTIMS WERE KILLED
WITH THE LONG GUN, THE NATURE OF
THOSE WOUNDS WOULD HAVE BEEN
EXTREMELY HORRIBLE.
>> AND, TOM, THE BUSHMASTER IS A
MILITARY-STYLE RIFLE.
IT'S NOT A SHOTGUN YOU WOULD USE
FOR HUNTING, YOU COULD SAY.
TELL ME WHAT YOU KNOW WHY A
CIVILIAN WOULD OWN THAT RIFLE?
>> WELL, ONE REASON WOULD BE
SOME CLAIM THAT IT HAS SPORTING
PURPOSES FOR EITHER HUNTING OR
EVEN JUST TARGET PRACTICE, AS A
SPORTING GUN.
BUT MOST PEOPLE THAT PURCHASE
THAT WEAPON CLAIM IT'S FOR
PERSONAL PROTECTION.
IT'S TO PROTECT THEIR HOMES OR
THEIR FAMILIES AND THEY WOULD
PREFER TO HAVE THAT KIND OF FIRE
POWER, AS OPPOSED TO A SHOTGUN
OR EVEN JUST PISTOLS WITHIN THE
HOME.
WE ALSO DON'T KNOW IF THERE WERE
GUNS THAT WERE RECOVERED THAT
HOME.
SHE MAY HAVE HAD SHOTGUNS, AS
WELL.
THE CHOICE OF THAT PARTICULAR
WEAPON, FRANKLY, OBVIOUSLY, IT'S
FOR HUNTING PEOPLE.
IT'S THE MAIN PURPOSE THAT YOU
WOULD WANT TO HAVE A WEAPON LIKE
THAT.
TO EITHER TAKE CARE OF YOURSELF
OR FOR PROTECTIVE PURPOSES,
CERTAINLY.
BUT A MUCH MORE POWERFUL GUN
THAN THOSE TWO HANDGUNS.
>> FOLLOW UP ON THAT, TOM.
ONE THING THAT THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER SAID THAT CAUGHT ME BY
SURPRISE WERE THAT THE BULLETS
WERE DESIGNED SOMEHOW TO STAY IN
THE TISSUE.
I'M NOT A GUN PERSON.
DWR DON
I DON'T KNOW A LOT ABOUT GUNS.
CAN YOU EXPLAIN TO ME WHAT THAT
MEANS?
>> AS A FORMER S.W.A.T TEAM
INSPECTOR, I'M NOT SURE WHAT HE
MEANS BY THAT.
THE .223 ROUND IS THE SAME ROUND
THAT WOULD BE FIRED OUT OF AN
M16.
IT HAS A MUZZLE VELOCITY OF OVER
215 FEET PER SECOND.
TO GET THAT BULLET TO SHOOT IN A
WAY THAT WOULD MAKE IT NOT FULLY
PENETRATE AND GO THROUGH TWO OR
THREE BODIES, FOR THAT MATTER,
I'M NOT QUITE CLEAR WHAT HE
MEANS BY HOW THAT WAS DESIGNED.
IF YOU SOFTEN THE LEAD OR, IN
THIS CASE, THE OUTER PART OF THE
BULLET WOULD HAVE A COPPER
JACKET AROUND IT SO THAT IT
WOULD FEED MORE EASILY THROUGH
THE GUN AS YOU'RE SHOOTING IT
AND PULLING THE TRIGGER.
THE OLD CASING IS EJECTED AND
THE NEW BULLET ISERED AND
YOU KEEP FIRING THAT WAY.
IT WOULD INTERFERE WITH THE
LOADING AND THE CONTINUED
ABILITY TO FIRE THAT WEAPON IN
RAPID SUCCESSION.
I'M NOT QUITE SURE WHAT HE MEANT
BY THAT.
>> ALL RIGHT.
FORMER FBI DIRECTOR TOM FUENTES.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR HELPING US
TRY TO UNDERSTAND THIS A LITTLE
BIT BETTER.
THANKS, TOM.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> BACK IN NEWTOWN, WE'RE
REMEMBERING THE VICTIMS.
DOING THAT QUITE A LOT.
SO MANY VICTIMS TO REMEMBER.
COMING UP, WE'LL HEAR FROM A
FATHER OF A 6-YEAR-OLD GIRL
KILLED IN THE ATTACK.
HE MOVED MANY PEOPLE TO TEARS
AND HOW HE WANTS US ALL TO
REMEMBER HIS LITTLE GIRL.
[ sniffs ] I HAVE A COLD.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
to the number 1 club
in the world.
The potential of
Manchester United unlocked.
NYSE Euronext.
Unlocking the world's potential.
When we got married.
I had three kids.
And she became the full time
mother of three.
It was soccer, and ballet, and
cheerleading, and baseball.
Those years were crazy.
So, as we go into
this next phase,
you know, a big part
of it for us is that
there isn't anything on the
schedule.
>>> THE FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS
HERE IN NEWTOWN HAVE BEEN
LARGELY SILENT.
INSTEAD OF CHOOSING TO GRIEVE
PRIVATELY, THEY ARE CHOOSING,
RATHER, TO GRIEVE PRIVATELY AND
WE'RE RESPECTING THAT PRIVACY
BEING CAREFUL NOT TO BARGE IN
AND TALK TO ANYONE WHO DOESN'T
WANT TO TALK TO US.
BUT ONE FATHER WANTED US TO KNOW
MORE ABOUT HIS DAUGHTER.
HER NAME WAS EMILIE PARKER AND
SHE WAS JUST 6 YEARS OLD.
>> EMILIE WAS A MENTOR TO HER
TWO LITTLE SISTERS IN FINDING
THE SIMPLE JOYS IN LIFE.
EMILIE'S LAUGHTER WAS INFECTIOUS
AND ALL THOSE WHO HAD THE
PLEASURE TO MEET HER WOULD AGREE
THIS WORLD IS A BETTER PLACE
BECAUSE SHE WAS IN IT.
SHE WAS THEIR BEST FRIEND.
THEY WERE ALL BORN WITHIN THREE
YEARS OF EACH OTHER, SO, BY LAW,
THEY'RE VERY CLOSE.
SHE WAS TEACHING MY MIDDLE
DAUGHTER TO READ.
SHE WOULD HELP MY YOUNGEST
DAUGHTER LEARN HOW TO MAKE
THINGS, SHOW HER HOW TO DO
CRAFTS.
THEY LOOKED UP TO HER.
AND THEY LOOK TO HER WHEN THEY
NEEDED COMFORT.
USUALLY THAT'S SAVED FOR A MOM
AND A DAD.
BUT IT WAS REALLY SWEET TO SEE
THE TIMES WHEN ONE OF THEM WOULD
FALL OR ONE WOULD GET THEIR
FEELINGS HURT AND HOW THEY WOULD
RUN TO EMILIE FOR SUPPORT AND
HUGS AND KISSES.
SHE WAS THE TYPE OF PERSON THAT
WOULD JUST LIGHT UP A ROOM.
SHE, SHE ALWAYS HAD SOMETHING
KIND TO SAY ABOUT ANYBODY.
HER LOVE AND THE STRENGTH THAT
SHE GAVE US AND THE EXAMPLE THAT
SHE SHOWED US IS REMARKABLE.
SHE IS AN INCREDIBLE PERSON.
AND I'M SO BLESSED TO BE HER
DAD.
I WAS LEAVING TO WORK AND SHE
WOKE UP BEFORE I LEFT AND I HAVE
ACTUALLY BEEN TEACHING HER
PORTUGUESE AND OUR LAST
CONVERSATION WAS IN PORTUGUESE
AND SHE TOLD ME GOOD MORNING AND
ASKED HOW I WAS DOING AND I SAID
THAT I WAS DOING WELL.
SHE SAID THAT SHE LOVED ME AND I
GAVE HER A KISS AND I WAS OUT
THE DOOR.
>> I SIMPLY DO NOT KNOW WHERE
ROBBIE PARKER, THIS MAN FOUND
THE STRENGTH AND COMPOSURE.
>> SO WELL SPOKEN.
HIS DAUGHTER, CLEARLY, SO
IMPORTANT TO HIM AND THAT FAMILY
SO CLOSE.
SO IMPRESSIVE.
THE PARKERS MOVED TO CONNECTICUT
FROM UTAH JUST EIGHT MONTHS AGO.
EMILIE IS GOING TO BE BURIED
BACK IN UTAH.
>> AS ROBBIE PARKER AND OTHER
PARENTS STRUGGLE WITH THE
TRAGEDY THAT HAPPENED HERE ON
FRIDAY, THEY ALSO FACE ANOTHER
CHALLENGE.
HOW TO EXPLAIN IT TO THEIR
CHILDREN.
SOMETHING WE WERE TALKING ABOUT
EARLIER.
HERE'S LISA SYLVESTER WITH SOME
EXPERT ADVICE.
>> IF THERE'S AN IMAGE THAT SUMS
UP THIS STORY, IT IS THIS.
ANY PARENT OUT THERE CAN RELATE.
PSYCHIATRIST CHARLES RASIN WITH
COLLEGE OF MEDICINE.
>> HOW DO YOU WRAP YOUR MIND
AROUND SOMETHING LIKE THIS, WITH
THE UNDERSTANDING THAT IT WILL
TAKE A WHILE AND THERE WILL BE
PEOPLE CLOSELY IMPACTED BY THIS
THAT WILL NEVER WRAP THEIR MIND
AROUND THIS.
HUMAN MINDS ARE NOT INFINITE AND
THIS IS APPEARING TO BE THE
WORST SCHOOLYARD CATASTROPHE IN
HISTORY.
THERE IS GOING TO BE A HUGE
LONG-TERM FALLOUT FOR THIS THAT
WILL IMPACT PEOPLE'S EMOTIONAL
WELL BEING AND WE NEED TO GEAR
OURSELVES FOR THIS FALLOUT
BECAUSE IT IS COMING.
>> THE NEWS OUT OF NEWTOWN IS
TRAUMATIC FOR PARENTS AND
CHILDREN.
THIS HAPPENED AT A SCHOOL WHERE
KIDS ARE SUPPOSED TO FEEL SAFE.
>> HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN THIS TO
CHILDREN?
AGAIN, IT DEPENDS ON THE AGE OF
THE CHILD.
SIMPLE, FORTHRIGHT EXPLANATIONS
ARE THE BEST.
I THINK ONE OF THE THINGS I TELL
CHILDREN IS THERE ARE SOME BAD
PEOPLE IN THE WORLD AND
SOMETIMES BAD PEOPLE DO REALLY
TERRIBLE THINGS.
AND A TERRIBLE THING HAS
HAPPENED AND THERE HAVE BEEN
SOME CHILDREN KILLED AND THIS IS
TERRIBLE, BUT YOU'RE SAFE.
AND, YOU KNOW, YOU'RE SAFE AND
YOU'RE IN A SITUATION NOW WHERE
WE'RE NOT GOING TO BE HARMED.
>> THE AMERICAN ACADEMY OF
PEDIATRICS OFFERS THIS ADVICE.
TAKE INTO ACCOUNT THE AGE OF THE
CHILD AND PROVIDE BASIC
INFORMATION, WITHOUT OFFERING
DETAILS THAT MAY ONLY ALARM
THEM.
ASK YOUR CHILDREN WHAT THEY
ALREADY KNOW AND ANSWER
QUESTIONS.
PARENTS CAN SHARE THEIR OWN
FEELINGS AND THE WAYS THEY'RE
COPING AND FIND MEANINGFUL WAYS
TO HELP OTHERS.
>> CHILDREN ARE RESILIENT AND
WHAT REALLY MATTERS NOW IS HOW
WE HELP THEM UNDERSTAND WHAT'S
HAPPENED, BUT EVEN I THINK MORE
IMPORTANT IS THE SENSE OF
PROTECTION AND SAFETY THAT WE
GIVE THEM STARTING THIS MOMENT
AND FOR THE NEXT WEEKS AND
MONTHS.
>> Reporter: FOR THOSE WHO
WITNESSED, THOSE CHILDREN WHO
SAW, THOSE WHO COVERED THEIR
EYES AND EARS TO SHUTOUT THE
HORROR, THEY NEED TIME, LOVE AND
PRAYERS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID IT THAT
PARENTS ARE GOING TO GO HOME,
HUG THEIR CHILDREN AND EVEN TO
PROCESS THIS AS A NATION, THAT'S
JUST GOING TO TAKE TIME.
>> THAT WAS CNN'S LISA
SYLVESTER.
FOR THOSE WHO NEED OR WANT GRIEF
COUNSELING, THE NEWTOWN GRIEF
COUNSELING IS GOING TO BE OPEN
FROM 9:00 TO 4:00 P.M.
NEWTOWN PARENT CONNECTION TRAUMA
SUPPORT SESSION WILL BE OPEN
FROM 2:00 P.M. TO 5:00 P.M.
TODAY.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
JILL AND HER MOUTH HAVE LIVED
A GREAT LIFE.
BUT SHE HAS SOME DENTAL ISSUES
SHE'S NOT HAPPY ABOUT.
SO I INTRODUCED JILL
TO CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SELECTED FOR PEOPLE OVER 50.
PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE IS A
TOOTHPASTE THAT DEFENDS AGAINST
TENDER, INFLAMED GUMS,
SENSITIVITY AND WEAK ENAMEL.
CONDITIONS PEOPLE OVER 50
EXPERIENCE.
CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SO JILL CAN KEEP LIVING
THE GOOD LIFE.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
I NEED YOU.
I FEEL SO ALONE.
BUT YOU'RE NOT
ALONE.
I KNEW YOU'D COME.
LIKE I COULD STAY AWAY.
YOU KNOW I CAN'T DO THIS
WITHOUT YOU.
YOU'LL NEVER HAVE TO.
YOU'RE ALWAYS THERE
FOR ME.
SHH!
I'LL GET YOU
A RENTAL CAR.
I COULD ALSO USE
AN UMBRELLA.
FALL IN LOVE WITH
PROGRESSIVE'S CLAIMS SERVICE.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, EVERYONE FOR OUR
CONTINUING SPECIAL COVERAGE OF
THE AWFUL SHOOTINGS THAT TOOK
PLACE HERE NOW FRIDAY MORNING,
TWO FULL DAYS AGO.
IT IS SUNDAY MORNING AND SO MANY
PEOPLE GOING TO CHURCH TO PRAY,
TO GRIEVE, TO MOURN.
HOW THEY'RE ALL DOING IT
TOGETHER HERE IN THIS TOWN.
>> I HAVE GOTTEN A SENSE AND I'M
SURE YOU HAVE, AS WELL.
I'VE BEEN TALKING TO MANY
RESIDENTS THAT ARE HERE AND MANY
OF OUR COLLEAGUES HAVE SAID THE
SAME THING.
IT'S A SMALL TOWN.
I'M STRUCK BY WE'RE IN THIS
BEAUTIFUL SETTING THIS MORNING.
THERE'S A CREEK RIGHT BESIDE US
AND IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
IT'S CHRISTMASTIME, THE HOLIDAY
SEASON AND ALL THE TREES AROUND
HERE AND THE TERROR AND TRAGEDY
THAT STRUCK THIS TOWN IS JUST
TRULY SHOCKING AND HOW CLOSE
THIS COMMUNITY HAS REALLY
RALLIED AROUND EACH OTHER AND
COME TOGETHER IS AWE INSPIRING.
WE SAW THOSE PICTURES FROM THAT
VIGIL IN STRATFORD, CONNECTICUT,
LAST NIGHT TO HONOR THE FIRST
GRADE TEACHER, VICTORIA SOTO.
A MASS OF HUMANITY THERE AND IT
HAPPENED VERY NATURALLY.
WASN'T EVEN A PLANNED EVENT.
>> THERE'S NO ONE HERE THAT THIS
HAS NOT TOUCHED IN SOME WAY.
I WAS AT A GAS STATION YESTERDAY
MORNING AND THE MAN BEHIND THE
COUNTER THERE HAD THIS LOOK ON
HIS FACE AND I WAS SAYING, YOU
KNOW, HOW HAS THIS BEEN FOR YOU
AND HE SAID, I'M AN EMT AND I
SPENT FRIDAY AT THE SCHOOL.
AND THEN SATURDAY HE WAS AT THE
GASSTATION, AGAIN.
AND IT WAS STILL CLEARLY
AFFECTING HIM SO, SO MUCH.
>> I THINK, JOHN, WE SEE IT
BECAUSE WE'RE REPORTING ON THE
STORY, BUT I THINK PEOPLE IN
THIS TOWN ARE JUST NOW STARTING
TO GET THE GRASP OF HOW THIS HAS
IMPACTED PEOPLE AROUND THE
WORLD.
WE RAN A CLIP OF KIND OF THE
GLOBAL REACTION AND HOW IT HAS
AFFECTED PEOPLE.
WHAT IT COMES DOWN TO, EVERYONE
KNOWS THE INNOCENCE OF AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL CHILD.
IF YOU DON'T HAVE CHILDREN, YOU
WERE ONCE IN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
YOURSELF.
I THINK EVERYONE HAS THAT
EXPERIENCE AND IT REALLY, IT
REALLY HITS HOME.
>> ONE OF MY FAVORITE COLUMNISTS
FROM "BOSTON GLOBE" MADE A
COMMENT KIDS AROUND THE WORLD
RIGHT NOW ARE WONDERING WHY
THEY'RE BEING HUGGED SO TIGHTLY
AND ALL I CAN SAY IS SIMPLY
ADORE THEM.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>>> ALL OF OUR HEARTS ARE HEAVY
THIS WEEKEND, OF COURSE, WITH
THE STORY OF THE DEADLY SHOOTING
HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
>> COMING UP, A REMINDER THAT WE
COULD ALL USE THAT GOOD THINGS,
THEY STILL DO HAPPEN.
Capella University understands
rough economic times
have led to an increase in
clinical depression.
Drug and alcohol abuse is up.
And those dealing with grief
don't have access to the
professional help they need.
When you see these issues, do
you want to walk away or
step up?
With a degree in the field of
Counseling or Psychology from
Capella University, you'll have
the knowledge to make
a difference in the lives of
others.
Let's get started at
CAPELLA.EDU
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
AWW MAN.
[ Male Announcer ] RETURNS
ARE EASY WITH FREE PICKUP
FROM THE U.S. POSTAL SERVICE.
WE'LL EVEN DROP OFF BOXES
IF YOU NEED THEM.
VISIT USPS.COM
PAY, PRINT,
AND HAVE IT PICKED UP FOR FREE.
ANY TIME OF YEAR.
♪
NICE SWEATER.
THANK YOU.
♪
SINCE AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL
WAS FOUNDED BACK IN 1894,
THEY'VE BEEN COMMITTED
TO PUTTING CLIENTS FIRST.
HELPING GENERATIONS
THROUGH TOUGH TIMES.
GOOD TIMES.
NEVER TAKING A BAILOUT.
THERE WHEN YOU NEED THEM.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
OVER THE CENTURIES.
THE STRENGTH OF
A GLOBAL FINANCIAL LEADER.
THE HEART OF
A ONE-TO-ONE RELATIONSHIP.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
WITH ODOR FREE ASPERCREME.
POWERFUL MEDICINE
RELIEVES PAIN FAST,
WITH NO ODOR.
SO ALL YOU NOTICE IS RELIEF.
ASPERCREME.