VIEWERS HERE IN THE UNITED
STATES AND AROUND THE WORLD.
HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW RIGHT NOW
ABOUT THIS DRAMATIC SITUATION
OF, THE MASSACRE THAT CLAIMED
THE LIVES OF 20 CHILDREN AND 6
ADULTS AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AUTHORITIES HAVE JUST RELEASED
THE FULL LIST OF THE VICTIMS'
NAMES.
12 GIRLS AND 8 BOYS.
THEY WERE SHOT AND KILLED.
ALL WERE EITHER 6 OR 7 YEARS
OLD.
WE'RE TOLD THEY WERE FIRST
GRADERS.
ALL SIX OF THE ADULTS KILLED AT
THE SCHOOL WERE WOMEN.
JUST MINUTES AGO, A MEDICAL
EXAMINER TOLD REPORTERS, ALL OF
THE VICTIMS DIED OF GUNSHOTS,
AND EVERYBODY WAS HIT MORE THAN
ONCE.
THREE GUNS WERE FOUND AT THE
SCENE, BUT THE MEDICAL EXAMINER
SAYS ALL OF THE WOUNDS HE KNOWS
OF WERE CAUSED BY WHAT HE CALLS
THE LONG WEAPON.
THAT WOULD BE THE MODIFIED
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE, THAT'S THE
CIVILIAN VERSION OF THE
MILITARY'S M-16.
CNN'S NATIONAL CORRESPONDENT
SUSAN CANDIOTTI IS WORKING HER
SOURCES.
WE'RE HEARING FROM THE GOVERNOR
OF CONNECTICUT, DAN MALLOY.
UPDATE OUR VIEWERS ON WHAT
YOU'RE LEARNING.
>> WOLF, TODAY WE ARE LEARNING
MORE FROM AUTHORITIES ABOUT --
THEY ARE PICKING UP MORE
EVIDENCE, BOTH AT THE SCENE,
CRIME SCENE, AS WELL AS AT THE
HOME THAT THE SHOOTER SHARED
WITH HIS MOTHER.
AND THEY ARE TRYING TO -- SAYING
IT IS BEGINNING TO EXPLAIN WHY
THIS HAPPENED.
NOW, THEY'RE NOT REVEALING
EXACTLY WHAT THAT INFORMATION
IS.
HOWEVER, AN OFFICIAL WITH THE
ATF IS TELLING US THAT, IN FACT,
MORE WEAPONS WERE FOUND AT THE
MOTHER'S HOME.
NOW, THEY ARE DOING COMPLETE
TRACES ON THOSE WEAPONS.
THEY ARE NOT SAYING THEY ARE
DIRECTLY RELATED TO THE
SHOOTING.
BUT IT IS PROVIDING MORE OF A
PICTURE ABOUT HOW EVERYTHING
HAPPENED.
WE HAVE, HOWEVER, LEARNED FROM
OUR SOURCES ABOUT THE THREE
ADDITIONAL WEAPONS THAT WERE
FOUND AT THE HOME.
APPEAR TO BE FOUND THERE.
AND THEY ARE ALL RIFLES.
ALL RIFLES.
THESE ARE IN ADDITION TO THE
THREE WEAPONS THAT WE'VE ALREADY
TOLD YOU ABOUT IN THE LAST
COUPLE OF DAYS.
TWO HANDGUNS, A GLOCK AND A SIG
SAUER.
AS WELL AS THAT SEMIAUTOMATIC
KNOWN AS A BUSHMASTER.
NOW, AUTHORITIES TELL US, OUR
SOURCES TELL US, THOSE THREE
WEAPONS WERE, IN FACT, FOUND
NEXT TO THE SHOOTER'S BODY AT
THE SCHOOL.
ONE WAS NOT IN ONE OF THE
VEHICLES OUTSIDE, BUT ALL THREE
WERE WITH HIM.
THEY ALSO DO KNOW WHICH ONE HE
USED TO KILL HIMSELF, ACCORDING
TO OUR SOURCES.
BUT THEY'RE NOT READY TO REVEAL
THAT YET, BECAUSE THEY CONSIDER
IT AN IMPORTANT PART OF THE
INVESTIGATION.
ALSO AT A NEWS CONFERENCE TODAY,
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER EXPLAINED
HOW VICIOUS THE ATTACKS WERE.
THAT THE VICTIMS WERE SHOT AT
CLOSE RANGE.
WOLF?
>> SUSAN, I'M GOING INTERRUPT,
BECAUSE THE GOVERNOR IS SPEAKING
RIGHT NOW.
DAN MALLOY, THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT.
>> ALL OF CONNECTICUT'S PEOPLE,
INDEED, THE PEOPLE OF THE WORLD,
WEEP FOR THE IMMEASURABLE LOSSES
SUFFERED BY THE FAMILIES AND
LOVED ONES OF THESE VICTIMS.
THOUGH WE COULD ALL TRY, WHEN
SOMETHING AS SENSELESS AS THIS
OCCURS, THERE'S PRECIOUS LITTLE
ANYONE CAN SAY TO THE FAMILIES
THAT WILL LESSEN THE HORROR AND
THE SENSE OF LOSS THEY FEEL.
WE COULD SAY WE FEEL THEIR PAIN,
BUT THE TRUTH IS, WE CAN'T.
WHEN TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS TAKE
PLACE, PEOPLE OFTEN LOOK FOR
ANSWERS, AN EXPLANATION OF HOW
THIS COULD HAVE HAPPENED.
BUT THE SAD TRUTH IS, THERE ARE
NO ANSWERS.
NO GOOD ONES, ANYWAY.
WE HAVE ALL SEEN TRAGEDIES LIKE
THIS PLAY OUT IN OTHER STATES
AND IN OTHER COUNTRIES.
EACH TIME WE HAVE WONDERED HOW
SOMETHING SO HORRIFIC COULD
OCCUR.
AND WE HAVE THANKED GOD THAT IT
DIDN'T HAPPEN HERE IN OUR
CONNECTICUT.
BUT NOW, SADLY IT HAS.
SO WHAT CAN WE DO?
AS WAS NO DOUBT THE CASE LAST
NIGHT, WE CAN HUG SOMEONE WE
LOVE A LITTLE TIGHTER.
AS HAS BEEN HAPPENING SINCE
YESTERDAY, WE CAN SHOW AND SHARE
WITH EACH OTHER THE GRIEF WE
FEEL FOR THE CHILDREN AND ADULTS
WHO WERE KILLED.
AND FOR THEIR FAMILIES AND THEIR
LOVED ONES.
WE CAN SPEAK ABOUT WHAT'S REALLY
IMPORTANT, AND WHAT CAN WAIT FOR
ANOTHER DAY.
THERE WILL BE TIMES SOON FOR A
DISCUSSION OF PUBLIC POLICY
ISSUES SURROUNDING YESTERDAY'S
EVENTS.
BUT WHAT'S IMPORTANT RIGHT NOW
IS LOVE, COURAGE AND COMPASSION.
LOVE, AS IT HAS POURED IN FROM
AROUND THE WORLD.
COURAGE AS IT WAS DEMONSTRATEDED
BY THE TEACHERS AND OTHER ADULTS
IN THE SCHOOL BUILDING WHOSE
ACTIONS NO DOUBT SAVED LIVES.
COURAGE ON DISPLAY AS IT ALWAYS
IS BY OUR FIRST RESPONDERS.
COMPASSION AS SHOWN BY PEOPLE
FROM AROUND CONNECTICUT WHO HAVE
ARRIVED IN NEWTOWN WANTING ONLY
TO HELP.
TOO OFTEN, WE FOCUS ON WHAT
DIVIDES US AS A PEOPLE.
INSTEAD OF WHAT BINDS US AS
HUMAN BEINGS.
WHAT WE SAW YESTERDAY WERE THOSE
BONDS.
THAT SENSE OF COMMUNITY.
IN THE COMING DAYS, WE WILL RELY
ON THAT WHICH WE HAVE BEEN
TAUGHT AND THAT WHICH WE
INHERENTLY BELIEVE.
THAT WE HAVE FAITH FOR A REASON,
AND THAT FAITH IS GOD'S GIFT TO
US ALL.
THOSE EDUCATORS AND THOSE
INNOCENT LITTLE BOYS AND GIRLS
WERE TAKEN FROM THEIR FAMILIES
FAR TOO SOON.
LET US ALL HOPE AND PRAY THOSE
CHILDREN ARE NOW IN A PLACE
WHERE THAT INNOCENCE WILL
FOREVER BE PROTECTED.
MAY GOD BLESS YOU.
AND MAY GOD BLESS THOSE 27
PEOPLE.
MAY GOD BLESS THEIR FAMILIES AND
FRIENDS.
AND MAY THE PAIN THEIR LOVED
ONES FEEL BE SOMEDAY ABSORBED BY
THE LOVE OF ALL MANKIND.
>> THE GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT,
DAN MALLOY, SPEAKING TO ALL THE
PEOPLE OF CONNECTICUT.
INDEED, THE ENTIRE COUNTRY,
ABOUT THIS HORRENDOUS TRAGEDY
HERE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
TRAGEDY NOW THAT IS BEGINNING --
THE ENORMITY OF THIS TRAGEDY
ONLY BEGINNING TO BE FELT WITH
THE RELEASE OF THE NAMES OF ALL
OF THE VICTIMS, 23 VICTIMS, 6
ADULTS, 20 CHILDREN.
THE NAMES HAVE NOW BEEN
RELEASED.
WE'RE ALSO LEARNING MORE ABOUT
THE FAMILY OF THE SHOOTER, ADAM
LANZA.
CNN'S ALI VELSHI HAS BEEN
TALKING TO NEIGHBORS, PEOPLE WHO
KNEW THIS 20-YEAR-OLD.
HE'S JOINING US NOW.
ALI, WHAT ARE YOU HEARING?
>> Reporter: WOLF, MORE
QUESTIONS COME OUT EVERY TIME WE
TRY AND FIND MORE INFORMATION.
YOU CAN'T SEE THE HOUSE, IT'S
BEHIND ME, BEHIND THAT POLICE
CAR YOU SEE.
THAT'S CORDONED OFF, STILL A
CRIME SCENE.
POLICE SAY THEY HAVE FOUND IT
QUITE FRUITFUL WHAT THEY HAVE
FOUND IN HERE.
WHAT WE KNOW ABOUT NANCY LANZA,
SHE LIVED ALONE WITH ADAM LANZA.
THE FAMILY LIVED ALONE SINCE
1998, THE WHOLE FAMILY, NANCY
LANZA, THE HUSBAND PETER LANZA,
THE SON RYAN, 24 YEARS OLD, AND
ADAM, WHO WAS 20 YEARS OLD.
WHAT HAPPENED IS PETER LANZA
LEFT THE HOUSE AT SOME POINT A
FEW YEARS AGO WHEN THEY
DIVORCED.
HE DOESN'T LIVE HERE ANYMORE.
RYAN LANZA, WHO IS 24 YEARS OLD,
WENT OFF TO WORK.
HE LIVED IN HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY.
WE SAW HE WAS TAKEN IN FOR
QUESTIONING YESTERDAY.
THAT LEFT ADAM AND NANCY BACK
HERE.
NANCY LANZA WORKED IN FINANCE IN
BOSTON AND HERE IN CONNECTICUT
FOR SOME YEARS.
BUT RECENTLY SHE HAS LEFT WORK.
WE DON'T KNOW WHETHER SHE WAS
RETIRING OR WHETHER SHE WAS
TAKING A BREAK.
SHE DID TELL ACQUAINTANCES SHE
WANTED TO TAKE CARE OF ADAM.
NOW, WE DID SPEAK TO ONE
NEIGHBOR, GENE J McDADE, WHO
SAID SHE DIDN'T FIND ANYTHING
UNUSUAL ABOUT THIS PARTICULAR
FAMILY.
>> SHE WAS A STAY-AT-HOME MOM
WHO LOVED HER KIDS.
THERE IS NO EXPLANATION.
THERE WAS NO FUNNY BUSINESS
GOING ON AS FAR AS I KNOW.
>> THEY WERE QUIET.
SEEMINGLY FRIENDLY PEOPLE.
I DON'T THINK PEOPLE IN THIS
NEIGHBORHOOD REALLY KNEW THEM
TOO WELL.
>> WERE THEY -- DID THEY
STRUGGLE, WERE THEY MORE SIMPLE?
>> I THINK THEY WERE WELL OFF,
BUT I CAN ONLY SPECULATE.
I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S NOT REALLY MY BUSINESS.
>> THAT WAS GINA McDADE'S SON,
JP.
I'LL TELL YOU, THE ONE QUESTION
THAT KEEPS COMING UP HERE, THIS
IS AN UPSCALE, AFLUENT FAMILY.
WHAT'S THE CONNECTION TO THE
GUNS?
SOME POLICE SOURCES ARE SAYING
ADAM MAY HAVE HAD ACCESS TO SIX
GUNS, TWO OF WHICH WERE USED IN
THE SHOOTINGS.
ONE WHICH WAS A SEMIAUTOMATIC
RIFLE, A BUSHMASTER, WHICH WAS
FOUND IN THE CAR.
AND THREE OTHER STANDARD RIFLES,
ONE OF THEM WAS AN M-FIELD.
WE DID SPEAK TO A LANDSCAPER IN
THE AREA WHO HAD ACTUALLY BEEN
INVOLVED IN PUTH UP CHRISTMAS
DECORATIONS, A LOT OF CHRISTMAS
DECORATIONS AROUND HERE VERY
RECENTLY FOR NANCY LANZA.
HE TOLD US THAT NANCY LANZA HAD
SHOWN HIM A RIFLE THAT SHE HAD
PURCHASED RECENTLY, THAT SHE WAS
A GUN ENTHUSIAST, AND SHE LIKED
TAKING HER KIDS TO TARGET
PRACTICE.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT THAT MEANS
AND WHERE THAT TARGET PRACTICE
WAS.
WE ALSO HAVE WORD FROM THE ATF
THAT THAT DOESN'T SEEM TO BE
TRUE.
SO WE'RE JUST TRYING TO GET TO
THE BOTTOM OF WHAT ROLE GUNS HAD
IN THIS FAMILY.
BUT FOR THE MOMENT, A LOT OF
THESE NEIGHBORS SAY THEY DIDN'T
REALLY KNOW THEM ALL THAT WELL,
EVEN THOUGH THEY LIVED IN THE
HOUSE SINCE 1998, WOLF.
>> SINCE 1998.
THEY HAVE LIVED THERE.
AND THEY WERE OBVIOUSLY VERY
QUIET, THESE FOLKS.
PEOPLE DIDN'T -- THEY WEREN'T
VERY SOCIABLE IS THAT THE
IMPRESSION YOU'RE GETTING?
>> Reporter: YEAH.
YOU KNOW, INITIALLY I THOUGHT IT
WAS THEY WEREN'T SOCIABLE.
IT JUST WAS THEY WEREN'T VERY
WELL-KNOWN AROUND THIS AREA.
IT'S A QUIET AREA, NO STREET
LIGHTS.
THE ONLY LIGHTS YOU SEE ARE FROM
OUR CAMERAS.
A QUIET AREA.
BOTH SONS ARE SAID TO HAVE
ENJOYED SKATEBOARDING.
BUT WE'RE NOT RUNNING INTO
PEOPLE WHO KNEW THEM.
I'LL TELL YOU ONE THING.
THESE NEIGHBORS ARE BEING VERY
QUIET.
MANY WERE EVACUATED OR TAKEN OUT
WHILE THE CRIME SCENE WAS BEING
COMBED.
AND MANY ARE IN THEIR HOMES BUT
THEIR LIGHTS ARE OFF.
WE SEE THEM LOOKING OUT.
WE DON'T WANT TO BE DISTURBING
PEOPLE WHO DON'T WANT TO TALK TO
US.
WE'RE NOT GETTING AS MUCH --
MAYBE THEY KNEW MORE PEOPLE,
MAYBE THEIR SOCIAL CIRCLE WAS
OUTSIDE OF THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
IT IS JUST UNUSUAL THAT IN A
PLACE LIKE THIS, AFTER HAVING
LIVED HERE FOR SO LONG, WE DON'T
HAVE A LOT OF PEOPLE COMING
FORWARD AND SAYING WE REALLY
KNEW THEM, HERE'S WHAT THEY WERE
LIKE.
WE DON'T REALLY HAVE A FULL
PICTURE YET.
>> IT IS UNFOLDING, IT IS
DEVELOPING.
THE KEY THING HERE IS WE KNOW
THAT NANCY STOPPED WORKING
RECENTLY.
WE'RE NOT QUITE SURE WHY.
AND WE'RE TRYING TO GET TO THE
BOTTOM OF THAT, WOLF.
>> ALI VELSHI, THANKS VERY MUCH.
WE'LL STAY IN CLOSE TOUCH WITH
YOU.
THERE IS CERTAINLY GOING TO BE A
LOT OF ATTENTION ON THE
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE, LIKE THE
ONE THAT THE MEDICAL EXAMINER
JUST SAID WAS USED TO SHOOT
EVERY ONE OF THE VICTIMS.
OUR CRIME AND JUSTICE
CORRESPONDENT JOE JOHNS HAS MORE
ON THE GUNS USED IN THE
SHOOTING.
JOE, TELL US WHAT YOU'RE
LEARNING.
>> WOLF, THE BUSHMASTER .223 IS
A WELL-KNOWN SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE
USED BY THE BELTWAY SNIPERS MORE
THAN A DECADE AGO TO WREAK HAVOC
HERE AROUND THE WASHINGTON, D.C.
AREA.
IT LOOKS LIKE A MILITARY WEAPON,
CERTAINLY FORMIDABLE, BUT IT HAS
ELEMENTS THAT CLEARLY MAKE IT A
HUNTING WEAPON.
AND NOW THE MEDICAL EXAMINER IN
CONNECTICUT SAYS ALL THE WOUNDS
HE KNOWS OF CAME FROM, QUOTE,
THE LONG GUN, WHICH ACCORDING TO
OUR UNDERSTANDING, IS THE
BUSHMASTER.
WHICH WAS CONFISCATED FROM THE
SHOOTING SCENE AND APPARENTLY
CAUSED ALL THE INJURIES TO THE
VICTIMS, THE MEDICAL EXAMINER
SAW.
ONE OF THE QUESTIONS WE'RE
ASKING RIGHT NOW IS WHETHER THAT
BUSHMASTER .223 FOUND ON THE
SCENE WOULD HAVE BEEN BANNED,
EITHER UNDER THE OLD FEDERAL
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN THAT PASSED
DURING THE CLINTON
ADMINISTRATION AND EXPIRED
DURING THE GEORGE W. BUSH YEARS.
WE ASKED A FORMER TOP OFFICIAL
OF THE FEDERAL BUREAU OF
ALCOHOL, TOBACCO AND FIREARMS
ABOUT THAT.
AND HE SAID IT JUST DEPENDS ON
HOW THE GUN WAS OUTFITTED, AND
SOME OF THESE THINGS WE DON'T
KNOW YET.
LISTEN.
>> UNDER THE ASSAULT WEAPON BAN,
A WEAPON LIKE THE BUSHMASTER
WOULD ONLY HAVE BEEN BANNED IF
IT HAD THINGS LIKE A FOLDING
STOCK, EXTENDED MAGAZINE, MORE
THAN TEN ROUNDS, I BELIEVE.
OR -- OTHER THAN FIXED SIGHTS,
THOSE KIND OF THINGS.
THOSE WOULD HAVE CAUSED IT TO
HAVE BEEN BANNED BEFORE.
>> OKAY.
SO HE'S TALKING ABOUT THE OLD
FEDERAL BAN.
NOW, BRESHARD SAYS THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT HAS ITS OWN ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN, BUT THIS BUSHMASTER
FOUND AT THE SCENE MIGHT NOT
HAVE BEEN COVERED BY THAT
EITHER.
THE BUSHMASTER RIFLE CERTAINLY
CAN BE CONSTRUED AS A SPORTING
RIFLE TO SHOOT SMALL ANIMALS.
THE WEAPON ADAM LANZA WAS USING
MIGHT HAVE BEEN LEGIT UNDER PAST
AND PRESENT LAW.
WOLF?
>> AND THE WEAPONS THAT WERE
FOUND THAT THEY BELIEVE WERE ALL
PURCHASED LEGALLY, RIGHT?
>> RIGHT.
LEGALLY BY NANCY LANZA.
THE MOTHER OF ADAM LANZA.
SHE, OF COURSE, WAS FOUND DEAD.
SO IT DOES APPEAR THAT THOSE
WERE PURCHASED LEGALLY BY THE
MOTHER, ADAM LANZA APPARENTLY
WOULD HAVE BEEN TOO YOUNG.
WE ALSO DO HAVE THAT REPORT THAT
ADAM LANZA TRIED TO PURCHASE A
GUN AT A DICK'S SPORTING GOODS
STORE EARLIER THIS WEEK BUT WAS
NOT ABLE TO DO THAT, WOLF.
>> YOU KNOW, IT'S HARD TO
BELIEVE THAT THIS IS GOING ON,
JOE.
AS WE TAKE A LOOK AT THE BIG
PICTURE, THE GUN DEBATE
CERTAINLY WILL BE INTENSIFIED AS
A RESULT OF WHAT'S GOING ON.
BUT CONNECTICUT HAS AMONG THE
TOUGHEST GUN LAWS IN THE
COUNTRY, RIGHT?
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
CONNECTICUT HAS A VERY STRICT
GUN LAW THERE.
AND THAT'S PART OF THE REASON
WHY AUTHORITIES WERE ABLE TO GO
BACK AND TRACE SO QUICKLY TO
FIND OUT THAT AT LEAST THE THREE
WEAPONS WE KNEW ABOUT AS OF
YESTERDAY HAD BEEN PURCHASED BY
THE MOTHER.
THAT WOULD BE THE SIG SAUER AS
WELL AS THE GLOCK, ALONG WITH
THIS BUSHMASTER.
SO THEY WERE ABLE TO FIGURE OUT
PRETTY QUICKLY, DUE TO
CONNECTICUT LAW, WHO HAD
PURCHASED THESE WEAPONS.
NONETHELESS, THIS STILL
HAPPENED.
OF COURSE, THAT'S ALL PART OF
THE WEAPONS DEBATE, AS YOU KNOW,
IN THE UNITED STATES.
AND TWICE NOW OVER THE PAST 24
HOURS THE PRESIDENT HAS MADE
REFERENCE TO SOME TYPE OF COMMON
SENSE LAWS THAT THE COUNTRY IS
GOING TO HAVE TO CONSIDER IN THE
DAYS AHEAD.
>> THIS DEBATE IS GOING TO
INTENSIFY.
THERE IS NO DOUBT ABOUT THAT.
THANKS VERY MUCH FOR THAT, JOE.
OUR OWN KATE BOLDUAN, SHE IS
ALSO HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
AND SHE HAS SPOKEN WITH A FAMILY
THAT HAD TWO CHILDREN IN THAT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, AND FOR A
LONG TIME COULD FIND ONLY ONE OF
THEM.
>> THE KIDS STARTED TO COME OUT.
AND WHEN I SAW HER, YOU KNOW,
THE SENSE OF RELIEF IS
INCREDIBLE, BUT IT'S REALLY
SHORT-LIVED, BECAUSE I STILL
HAVE ONE IN THERE.
AND I'M WAITING FOR HIM TO COME.
AND HE DIDN'T COME OUT.
AND I DIDN'T SEE HIS TEACHER AND
I DIDN'T SEE HIS CLASSMATES.
♪
[ Woman ]
♪ WHAT I WANT THIS SEASON
♪ IF YOU'D LIKE
TO TRY AND GUESS ♪
♪ IT IS SOMETHING VERY SPECIAL
♪ I WOULD READILY CONFESS
[ dogs barking ]
♪ 'CAUSE ALL I WANT
THIS SEASON ♪
♪ IS SOMETHING FROM YOUR HEART
♪ LA DA DA, LA DA DA
[ Male Announcer ] THINKING
OF OTHERS THIS HOLIDAY SEASON,
TRAVELERS.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE WAY IT MOVES.
THE WAY IT CLEANS.
EVERYTHING ABOUT
THE ORAL-B POWER BRUSH
IS SIMPLY REVOLUTIONARY.
ORAL-B POWER BRUSHES OSCILLATE,
ROTATE
AND EVEN PULSATE
TO GENTLY LOOSEN AND BREAK UP
THAT STICKY PLAQUE
WITH MORE BRUSH MOVEMENTS
THAN MANUAL BRUSHES
AND EVEN
UP TO 50% MORE
THAN LEADING
SONIC TECHNOLOGY BRUSHES
FOR A SUPERIOR CLEAN.
ORAL-B POWER BRUSHES.
GO TO ORALB.COM
FOR THE LATEST OFFERS.
>>> FAMILY MEMBERS OF A
6-YEAR-OLD WHO WAS KILLED AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL NOW ARE
SPEAKING OUT.
LISTEN IN.
>> I HOPPED INTO AN AIRPLANE AND
LEFT.
I DIDN'T KNOW THE STATUS OF MY
NIECE UNTIL WE ARRIVED IN
ATLANTA ON OUR WAY TO COME HERE.
AND IT WAS UNIMAGINABLE.
AND AS WE SHED TEARS IN ATLANTA,
WE HAD NO IDEA THAT THIS WAS
SOMETHING THAT THE WHOLE COUNTRY
KNEW ABOUT OR EVEN HEARD ABOUT.
AND WE WERE GETTING HUGS AND
SUPPORT THROUGH THE ATLANTA
AIRPORT.
WE WERE USHERED IN THROUGH.
WE WERE GIVEN SO MANY WORDS OF
COMPASSION AND CARING FROM
OTHERS, STRANGERS.
IT WAS UNBELIEVABLE.
MY BROTHER-IN-LAW WOULD LIKE TO
SAY SOME WORDS, BUT BEFORE I
HAVE HIM TALK, I JUST WANT TO
SAY THAT EMILY ALICE PARKER WAS
THE SWEETEST LITTLE GIRL I HAVE
EVER KNOWN.
MY CHILDREN ARE GRIEVING.
MY SIBLINGS ACROSS THE COUNTRY
ARE GRIEVING.
AND WE'RE JUST DEVASTATED THAT
SOMEONE SO BEAUTIFUL AND PERFECT
IS NO LONGER GOING TO BE IN OUR
LIVES.
AND FOR NO REASON.
AND WE CAN ONLY PRAY WE FIND
UNDERSTANDING IN THE DAYS AND
WEEKS TO COME.
AND ONE DAY FIND PEACE.
BUT WE WERE ALL BLESSED TO HAVE
KNOWN HER.
AND TO HAVE HAD HER IN OUR
LIVES.
THERE'S BEEN A FUND THAT WAS SET
UP BY MEMBERS OF OUR FAMILIES
AND FRIENDS BACK IN UTAH THAT
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN DONATING TO,
AND WE WOULD LIKE TO THANK ALL
OF YOU FOR YOUR DONATIONS TO
THAT.
WE'RE HOPING TO BE ABLE TO USE
THAT TO BRING EMILIE BACK TO
UTAH FOR HER FINAL RESTING PLACE
WITH HER FAMILY THERE.
AND WE WANT TO THANK ALL OF YOU
WHO MADE THOSE DONATIONS.
I WILL TURN THIS TO ROB PARKER.
>> WE'RE WAITING TO HEAR FROM
THE FATHER NOW OF THIS
6-YEAR-OLD, EMILIE PARKER, SHOT
AND KILLED IN THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL YESTERDAY.
THAT WAS -- THAT WAS EMILIE
PARKER'S AUNT WHO WAS SPEAKING,
AND HER FATHER, EMILIE PARKER'S
FATHER, ROBBY PARKER IS GOING TO
BE SPEAKING RIGHT NOW.
THE FAMILY WANTED TO SPEAK AND
WANTED TO MAKE IT CLEAR THEY
WANTED TO REMEMBER LITTLE EMILIE
PARKER, AND WE JUST HEARD WHAT A
WONDERFUL YOUNG LITTLE
SIX-YEAR-OLD GIRL SHE WAS.
HOW SAD OF A STORY THIS IS.
IT GETS SADDER AND SADDER AS WE
LEARN MORE DETAILS OF THESE
YOUNG KIDS AND THE SIX ADULTS
SHOT AND KILLED AT THAT SCHOOL.
26 VICTIMS, 20 CHILDREN.
6 AND 7-YEAR-OLD FIRST GRADERS
MOSTLY SHOT FOR NO REASON AT
ALL.
AND SIX ADULTS, MOSTLY TEACHERS,
ALL WOMEN, SHOT AND KILLED, AS
WELL.
ONCE AGAIN, ROBBY PARKER, THE
FATHER OF 6-YEAR-OLD EMILIE
PARKER, IS SUPPOSED TO COME TO
THE MICROPHONES.
I ASSUME HE'S CONSOLING THE
SISTER RIGHT NOW.
AND HE WILL HAVE THE STRENGTH --
THIS IS THE DECISION THAT THE
PARKER FAMILY WANTED TO DO.
THEY WANTED TO COME TO THE
MICROPHONES.
THEY WANTED TO SPEAK ABOUT
EMILIE PARKER.
AND THAT IS SOMETHING THAT WE
HAVE SEEN NOW THAT -- PRESUMABLY
WE'LL SEE A LITTLE BIT MORE,
PEOPLE WANTING TO REMEMBER THEIR
LOVED ONES AND SPEAKING OUT.
IT'S NOT UNUSUAL IN A SITUATION
LIKE THIS.
I REMEMBER AT VIRGINIA TECH WHEN
I WENT OUT THERE, PARENTS, LOVED
ONES OF SLAIN YOUNG PEOPLE
WANTED TO REMEMBER THEIR SONS
AND THEIR DAUGHTERS, AND AS A
RESULT THEY SPOKE AND MADE A
STATEMENT.
SO WE'LL SEE IF ROBBY PARKER --
I ASSUME HE'S GOING TO COME OUT
TO THE MICROPHONES NOW.
AND MAKE A STATEMENT.
IT LOOKS LIKE THE FAMILY IS
THERE.
AND THEY'RE GETTING READY TO
MAKE -- TO COME TO THE MIKE
REPHONE.
WE'LL LISTEN IN.
>> OKAY.
SO MY NAME IS ROBBY PARKER.
MY FAMILY IS ONE OF THE FAMILIES
THAT LOST A CHILD YESTERDAY.
IN THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL SHOOTINGS HERE IN
CONNECTICUT.
I'VE BEEN CONTACTED BY SO MANY
PEOPLE AND AGENCIES WANTING TO
KNOW HOW WE'RE DOING AND I JUST
THOUGHT THAT THIS MIGHT BE THE
BEST WAY TO SHARE THOSE FEELINGS
WITH EVERYBODY.
FIRST OF ALL, I WOULD REALLY
LIKE TO OFFER OUR DEEPEST
CONDOLENCES TO ALL OF THE
FAMILIES WHO WERE DIRECTLY
AFFECTED BY THIS SHOOTING.
IT'S AN HORRIFIC TRAGEDY, AND WE
WANT EVERYBODY TO KNOW THAT OUR
HEARTS AND OUR PRAYERS GO OUT TO
THEM.
THIS INCLUDES THE FAMILY OF THE
SHOOTER.
I CAN'T IMAGINE HOW HARD THIS
EXPERIENCE MUST BE FOR YOU.
AND I WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT OUR
FAMILY AND OUR LOVE AND OUR
SUPPORT GOES OUT TO YOU AS WELL.
AT THIS TIME, OUR THANKS GO OUT
TO SO MANY PEOPLE, SO MANY
FRIENDS AND FAMILY.
AND COMPLETE STRANGERS WHO WE
DON'T KNOW.
FOR ALL THE LOVE, CONDOLENCES
AND IS SUPPORT YOU'VE GIVEN TO
US.
MY DAUGHTER EMILIE WOULD BE ONE
OF THE FIRST ONES TO BE STANDING
AND GIVING HER LOVE AND SUPPORT
TO ALL THOSE VICTIMS.
BECAUSE THAT'S THE TYPE OF
PERSON THAT SHE IS.
NOT BECAUSE OF ANY PARENTING
THAT MY WIFE AND I COULD HAVE
DONE.
BUT BECAUSE THOSE WERE THE GIFTS
THAT WERE GIVEN TO HER BY HER
HEAVENLY FATHER.
AS THE DEEP PAIN BEGINS TO
SETTLE INTO OUR HEARTS, WE FIND
COMFORT REFLECTING ON THE
INCREDIBLE PERSON THAT EMILIE
WAS, AND HOW MANY LIVES SHE WAS
ABLE TO TOUCH IN HER SHORT TIME
HERE ON EARTH.
EMILIE WAS BRIGHT, CREATIVE AND
VERY LOVING.
EMILIE WAS ALWAYS WILLING TO TRY
NEW THINGS, OTHER THAN FOOD.
SHE LOVED TO USE HER TALENTS TO
IT TOUCH THE LIVES OF EVERYONE
SHE CAME INTO CONTACT WITH.
SHE WAS AN EXCEPTIONAL ARTIST,
AND SHE ALWAYS CARRIED AROUND
HER MARKERS AND PENCILS SO SHE
NEVER MISSED AN OPPORTUNITY TO
DRAW A PICTURE OR MAKE A CARD
FOR THOSE AROUND HER.
I CAN'T COUNT THE NUMBER OF
TIMES EMILIE NOTICED SOMEONE
FEELING SAD OR FRUSTRATED AND
WOULD RUSH TO FIND A PIECE OF
PAPER TO DRAW THEM A PICTURE OR
TO WRITE THEM AN ENCOURAGING
NOTE.
EMILIE'S CARD-MAKING WAS
EXPRESSED BEAUTIFULLY THIS LAST
OCTOBER WHEN SHE PLACED A VERY
SPECIAL CARD SHE HAD MADE INTO
THE CASKET WITH HER GRANDPA, WHO
ALSO JUST RECENTLY DIED OF A
TRAGIC ACCIDENT.
EMILIE WAS A MENTOR TO HER TWO
LITTLE SISTERS IN DELIGHTING AND
TEACHING THEM HOW TO READ, DANCE
AND FIND THE SIMPLE JOYS IN
LIFE.
EMLIE'S LAUGHTER WAS INFECTIOUS,
AND ALL WOULD AGREE THIS WORLD
WAS A BETTER PLACE BECAUSE SHE
HAS BEEN IN IT.
AS WE MOVE ON FROM WHAT HAPPENED
HERE, WHAT HAPPENED TO SO MANY
PEOPLE, LET IT NOT TURN INTO
SOMETHING THAT DEFINES US.
BUT SOMETHING THAT INSPIRES US
TO BE BETTER, TO BE MORE
COMPASSIONATE, AND MORE HUMBLE
PEOPLE.
LET US PLEASE KEEP THE
SENTIMENTS OF LOVE WE FEEL FOR
OUR FAMILIES AND THE COMPASSION
WE FEEL FOR OTHERS, EVEN
COMPLETE STRANGERS, AND KEEP
THEM WITH US AT ALL TIMES.
NOT JUST IN TIMES OF SORROW AND
TRAGEDY.
AND MAY WE DO THIS SO WE CAN
BETTER ALL OF OUR COMMUNITIES
AND ALL OF OUR CITIES AND ALL
OUR STATES SO WE CAN MAKE
EVERYONE EVERYWHERE IN THIS
COUNTRY FEEL SAFE.
THANK YOU.
I WOULD BE HAPPY TO ANSWER ANY
QUESTIONS, AS LONG AS I SEE THEM
TO BE WITHIN REASON.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> I WAS LEAVING TO WORK, AND
SHE WOKE UP BEFORE I LEFT.
AND I'VE ACTUALLY BEEN TEACHING
HER PORTUGUESE.
SO OUR LAST CONVERSATION WAS IN
PORTUGUESE.
AND SHE TOLD ME GOOD MORNING,
AND ASKED HOW I WAS DOING.
AND I SAID THAT I WAS DOING
WELL.
SHE SAID THAT SHE LOVED ME.
AND I GAVE HER A KISS AND I WAS
OUT THE DOOR.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> THE BEST WAY THAT I'VE BEEN
SEEING THAT IS I HAVE TWO REALLY
GOOD FRIENDS AT HOME WHO HAVE
SET UP A FACEBOOK PAGE TO HELP
RAISE MONEY FOR EMILIE.
AND WHEN I'VE GOTTEN ON THAT AND
JUST SEEN THE NUMBER OF PEOPLE
WHO HAVE COMMENTED AND EXPRESSED
THEIR CONDOLENCES, IT'S BEEN
QUITE OVERWHELMING.
>> CAN YOU DESCRIBE WHAT YOUR
DAUGHTER LOOKED LIKE FOR US?
>> THERE'S LOTS OF PICTURES ON
THE EMILIEPARKER FUND PAGE ON
FACEBOOK.
SHE WAS BEAUTIFUL.
SHE WAS BLONDE, ALWAYS SMILING.
BRIGHT BLUE EYES.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> HERE AT THE CHURCH LAST
NIGHT, THERE WAS A SPECIAL
MEETING, AND I WAS GIVEN AN
OPPORTUNITY TO BE ABLE TO SPEAK
AT THAT, AS WELL.
AND IN THAT, I JUST MENTIONED
THAT, YOU KNOW, THE PERSON THAT
CHOSE TO ACT IN THIS WAY WAS
ACTING WITH A GOD-GIVEN RIGHT
THAT HE WAS GIVEN BY GOD TO --
WITH HIS OWN FREE AGENCY.
AND THAT FREE AGENCY IS GIVEN TO
ALL OF US TO ACT AND CHOOSE TO
DO WHATEVER WE WANT.
AND GOD CAN'T TAKE THAT AWAY
FROM US.
AND I KNOW THAT THAT'S SOMETHING
THAT HE WAS GIVEN AND THAT'S
WHAT HE CHOSE TO DO WITH IT.
AND I KNOW THAT GOD CAN'T TAKE
THAT AWAY.
I'M NOT MAD.
BECAUSE I HAVE MY AGENCY TO MAKE
SURE THAT I USE THIS EVENT TO DO
WHAT I CAN TO DO WHATEVER I CAN.
SO I WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT MY
FAMILY AND MY WIFE AND MY
DAUGHTERS ARE TAKEN CARE OF AND
THAT IF THERE'S ANYTHING THAT I
CAN DO TO HELP ANYBODY AT ANY
TIME, ANYWHERE, THAT I WOULD BE
WILLING TO DO THAT.
>> MR. PARKER, YOU TALK ABOUT
YOUR DAUGHTER.
YOUR OTHER DAUGHTERS, I WONDER
IF YOU COULD TALK ABOUT THEM.
>> AS UNCHEESY AS I CAN SAY
THAT, SHE WAS THEIR BEST FRIEND.
THEY WERE ALL BORN WITHIN THREE
YEARS OF EACH OTHER.
SO BY LAW, THEY'RE VERY CLOSE.
SHE WAS TEACHING MY MIDDLE
DAUGHTER TO READ.
SHE WOULD HELP MY YOUNGEST
DAUGHTER LEARN HOW TO MAKE
THINGS, SHOW HER HOW TO DO
CRAFTS.
THEY LOOKED UP TO HER.
AND THEY LOOKED TO HER WHEN THEY
NEEDED COMFORT.
USUALLY THAT'S SAVED FOR A MOM
AND DAD.
BUT IT WAS REALLY SWEET TO SEE
THE TIMES WHEN ONE OF THEM WOULD
FALL OR GET THEIR FEELINGS HURT,
HOW THEY WOULD RUN TO EMILIE FOR
SUPPORT AND HUGS AND KISSES.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> YOU KNOW, IT'S HARD FOR ME TO
TALK ABOUT, BECAUSE I WAS AT
WORK AT THE HOSPITAL.
AND THE HOSPITAL IS IN LOCKDOWN,
SO I COULDN'T GET TO THE SCHOOL
RIGHT AWAY.
I LOVE THE PEOPLE AT THE SCHOOL.
I LOVE EMILIE'S TEACHER.
AND THE CLASSMATES THAT WE WERE
ABLE TO GET TO KNOW.
I LOVE ALL OF THEM.
AND MY PRAYERS GO OUT TO ALL OF
THOSE PEOPLE.
>> IS THERE ANYTHING YOU WANT TO
SHARE WITH THE OTHER PARENTS?
>> THE ONLY THING I CAN SAY TO
OTHER PARENTS IS THE COMFORT WE
CAN FIND, AT LEAST WE KNOW
THERE'S OTHER PEOPLE THAT ARE IN
THE SAME BOAT THAT WE ARE.
THAT THERE'S OTHER PEOPLE THAT
KNOW HOW YOU'RE FEELING.
AND EVEN THOUGH WE ARE GOING
THROUGH IT DIFFERENTLY AND OUR
EMOTIONS ARE DIFFERENT, AND
WE'RE GOING TO PROCESS THIS
WHOLE THING DIFFERENTLY, WE'RE
IN THIS TOGETHER AND WE'RE
FOREVER LINKED BY THIS EVENT.
>> HAVE YOU SPOKEN TO YOUR OTHER
CHILDREN ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED?
>> YEAH, WE WERE ABLE TO -- YOU
KNOW, WITH THE EVENTS THAT
HAPPENED WITH MY FATHER-IN-LAW
RECENTLY, THIS IS UNFORTUNATELY
A TOPIC THAT'S BEEN DISCUSSED IN
OUR FAMILY OVER THE LAST COUPLE
MONTHS.
SO WITH MY DAUGHTERS WE HAVE
BEEN ABLE TO EXPRESS TO THEM
WHAT HAPPENED.
THEIR UNDERSTANDING IS A LITTLE
LIMITED, OF COURSE.
BUT THEY SEEM TO GET THE FACT
THAT THEY HAVE SOMEBODY THAT
THEY'RE GOING TO MISS VERY MUCH.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> THE WHAT?
I'M SORRY.
>> EMILIE'S TEACHER.
>> YOU KNOW, WITH RESPECT TO HER
FAMILY, I'M NOT GOING TO SAY HER
NAME.
I MET HER AT PARENT-TEACHER
CONFERENCE A COUPLE WEEKS AGO,
AND WAS SO IMPRESSED WITH THE
FACT THAT SHE REALLY SEEMED TO
KNOW EMILIE AS A PERSON.
EMILIE'S LIKES AND DISLIKES AND
THINGS SHE WAS GOOD AT AND
FRUSTRATED HER.
AND IS THE WAY SHE TALKED ABOUT
EMILIE LIKE THAT, I KNEW WITHOUT
A DOUBT SHE KNEW ALL OTHER 16
KIDS IN THE CLASSROOM THE EXACT
SAME.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> YOU KNOW, THE WORD OF THIS
GETS OUT IN THE AFTERNOON, AND
OUR FAMILY IS FROM OUT WEST.
GETTING THEM HERE IN A TIMELY
MANNER WAS KIND OF DIFFICULT.
THE FACT THAT, YOU KNOW, AIRLINE
AGENCIES WERE BENDING OVER
BACKWARDS AND BREAKING RULES,
WHICH THEY NEVER DO, WAS QUITE
AMAZING.
PEOPLE -- JUST SEEING MY FAMILY
IN THE AIRPORT AND REALIZING
THAT SOMETHING WAS WRONG BUT NOT
KNOWING EXACTLY WHAT WAS WRONG
AND GIVING THEM HUGS AND THEIR
SUPPORT, YOU KNOW -- EVERYTHING
FROM PEOPLE GETTING OUT OF LINE
IN THE SECURITY LINE TO LET THEM
PASS AND MOVING SEATS ON THE
AIRPLANE SO THEY COULD SIT
TOGETHER.
THOSE KIND OF THINGS WERE VERY
GREATLY APPRECIATED.
AND ANYBODY THAT PROVIDED THOSE
R MY FAMILY, I JUST THANK YOU
SO MUCH.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> SHE WAS THE TYPE OF PERSON
THAT COULD JUST LIGHT UP A ROOM.
SHE ALWAYS HAD SOMETHING KIND TO
SAY ABOUT ANYBODY.
HER LOVE AND STRENGTH SHE GAVE
US AND THE EXAMPLE SHE SHOWED TO
US IS REMARKABLE.
SHE IS AN INCREDIBLE PERSON.
AND I'M SO BLESSED TO BE HER
DAD.
I GUESS THAT'S IT.
YEAH.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW HOW TO GET THROUGH
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
MY WIFE AND I DON'T UNDERSTAND
HOW TO PROCESS ALL OF THIS AND
HOW TO GET OUR LIVES GOING.
YOU KNOW, WE FIND STRENGTH IN
OUR RELIGION AND IN OUR FAITH.
AND IN OUR FAMILY.
AND I THINK THAT EVERYBODY
THAT'S GOING THROUGH SOMETHING
LIKE THIS HAS HOPEFULLY SUPPORT
WITH THEIR FAMILY, AND WITH WHAT
OTHER MEANS THEY CAN FIND.
I JUST HOPE EVERYBODY CAN GET
THE HELP THEY NEED.
SINCE NOBODY KNOWS HOW TO GO
THROUGH THIS, I THINK IT'S
REALLY IMPORTANT THAT PEOPLE
REACH OUT TO THE SERVICES THAT
HAVE BEEN PROVIDED TO ALL OF US
FOR COUNSELING AND SOMEBODY TO
TALK TO AND UNDERSTANDING HOW TO
TALK TO YOUR CHILDREN AND THOSE
KIND OF THINGS.
I REALLY HOPE THAT ALL OF US
UTILIZE THOSE THINGS THAT HAVE
BEEN OFFERED TO US.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> I HAD A 3, 4 AND 6-YEAR-OLD.
>> IT WENT FROM SOMETHING THAT,
YOU KNOW, I -- I CAN'T IMAGINE
THIS IS HAPPENING.
THIS HAS TO BE SOME SORT OF
MISTAKE.
WHAT WAS HARD, SINCE I WAS AT
WORK, I WAS HAVING TO TALK TO MY
WIFE ON THE PHONE.
AND JUST TRYING TO KNOW WHAT WAS
THE RIGHT THING TO DO.
YOU KNOW, WE DIDN'T -- I DIDN'T
THINK IT WAS THAT BIG A DEAL AT
FIRST.
I THOUGHT WITH THE FIRST REPORTS
THAT WERE COMING IN, IT DIDN'T
SOUND LIKE IT WAS GOING TO BE AS
TRAGIC AS IT WAS.
AND THEN AS WE WEREN'T GIVEN
INFORMATION IT STARTED TO SETTLE
IN THAT IT WAS A MUCH TOUGHER
EXPERIENCE FOR EVERYBODY.
AND SO THAT WAS KIND OF WHAT IT
WAS LIKE FOR US.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> I'M PROUD TO SAY THAT I'M A
PHYSICIAN ASSISTANT AND I WORK
IN THE DANBURY-NEWBORN INTENSIVE
CARE UNIT.
I'M 30 YEARS OLD.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> THE BEST THING THAT I CAN
THINK OF TO DO TO MOVE ON IS TO
HELP OTHER PEOPLE.
WHEN YOU HELP OTHER PEOPLE, YOU
FEEL BETTER ABOUT YOURSELF.
AND THE MORE PEOPLE HELP OTHER
PEOPLE THAN THEN THE MORE PEOPLE
ARE BLESSED.
AND WHEN YOUR LIFE FEELS
BLESSED, YOU FEEL LIKE YOU CAN
TAKE ON THE WORLD.
>> YOU WORK AT THE DANBURY
HOSPITAL?
>> YES.
>> YOU WORK WITH NEWBORNS?
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> I WAS AT WORK WHEN MY WIFE
CALLED ME.
AND THEN I WAS ABLE TO FIND A
TELEVISION AND START TRYING TO
GET ANY INFORMATION I CAN.
>> WERE YOU THERE WHEN ANY OF
THE CHILDREN --
>> I WASN'T.
I DON'T WORK IN THE EMERGENCY
ROOM, SO I WASN'T INVOLVED WITH
ANY OF THAT.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> YOU KNOW WHAT'S INTERESTING
ABOUT THAT, MY FAMILY JUST MOVED
TO NEWTOWN ABOUT EIGHT MONTHS
AGO.
WHEN I ACCEPTED THE JOB HERE.
SO THE IMPRESSION I GOT FROM
PEOPLE ON THE EAST COAST WAS A
LOT DIFFERENT FROM WHAT I
EXPERIENCED WHEN I GOT HERE,
THAT'S FOR SURE.
EVERYBODY THAT -- EVERYTHING
THAT EVERYBODY WAS TELLING ME
OUT WEST WAS THAT I WAS IN FOR A
RUDE AWAKENING.
BUT THE PEOPLE HERE HAVE BEEN
AMAZING.
AND I'VE NEVER MET SO MANY
PEOPLE THAT WERE WILLING TO HELP
US WHEN WE MOVED HERE TO GET
ESTABLISHED TO GETTING TO KNOW
ME AND MY FAMILY.
I TRULY LOVE IT HERE.
AND I'M GLAD TO BE HERE.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> I KEEP HEARING THAT.
I HAVEN'T REALLY HAD THE
TELEVISION ON MUCH OR ANYTHING
LIKE THAT.
SO I DON'T QUITE UNDERSTAND OR
GRASP THE GRANDNESS OF THE -- OF
EVERYBODY'S SUPPORT FROM AROUND
THE WORLD, OTHER THAN JUST THE
FEELING THAT WE GET WITH
EVERYBODY'S PRAYERS.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> YOU KNOW, YOU CAN NEVER STOP
BEING THE BEST PARENT YOU CAN
BE.
YOU CAN ALWAYS BE BETTER.
YOU CAN ALWAYS BE MORE PATIENT.
YOU CAN ALWAYS BE MORE LOVING
AND UNDERSTANDING.
AND WILLING TO ACCEPT YOUR
CHILDREN FOR WHO THEY ARE.
I REALLY HOPE THAT AS I CONTINUE
TO BE A DAD TO MY TWO CHILDREN
THAT I CAN JUST -- IF ANYBODY
LOOKS BACK ON MY LIFE, THE
NUMBER ONE THING THEY CAN SAY
ABOUT ME WAS THAT I WAS A GREAT
DAD AND MY CHILDREN LOVED ME
BECAUSE OF THE FATHER I WAS.
THANKS, GUYS.
>>> ROBBIE PARKER, WHOSE
DAUGHTER, 6-YEAR-OLD EMILIE
PARKER SHOT YESTERDAY.
SANJAY GUPTA WATCHED WITH ME.
SANJAY, WHAT CAN YOU SAY?
THIS IS ONE FATHER, ONE PARENT,
19 OTHER CHILDREN WERE MURDERED
YESTERDAY HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AS WELL.
AND HIS POWERFUL WORDS CERTAINLY
RESONATE.
>> HE SAID SHE LIKED TO CARRY
AROUND CRAYONS AND PAPER AND SHE
WOULD MAKE A CARD FOR PEOPLE
WHEN THEY WERE FRUSTRATED AND
NOT FEELING WELL.
HE SAID HE TALKED ABOUT HIS
THREE DAUGHTERS, YOU KNOW, 3, 4
AND 6.
AND HE SAID 6-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHTER -- HE STILL TALKS ABOUT
HER, OBVIOUSLY.
THIS IS SO SO RAW FOR HIM.
I HAVE THREE DAUGHTERS MYSELF,
WOLF, AS YOU KNOW.
I JUST CAN'T IMAGINE.
WE TALK SO MUCH, WOLF, ABOUT HOW
PEOPLE ARE GOING TO OVERCOME
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
IT IS JUST SO -- IT IS JUST --
IT'S SO UNHUMAN TO THINK THAT
YOU OUTLIVE YOUR CHILDREN.
AND I DON'T KNOW HOW, YOU
KNOW -- WHEN YOU HEAR HIM TALK
LIKE THAT, HE WANTS TO EMPOWER
HIMSELF.
HE WANTS TO TURN THIS INTO SOME
SORT OF -- YOU KNOW, HE WANTS TO
TURN IT INTO SOMETHING WHERE HE
CAN HELP OTHER PEOPLE.
AND THAT'S HOW HE'S GOING TO
HELP GET HIMSELF THROUGH THIS.
BUT I DIDN'T THINK I WOULD BE
ABLE TO DO THIS LOVE SHOT WITH
YOU, WOLF, JUST LISTENING TO
HIM.
YOU KNOW, IT'S JUST SO TOUGH TO
HEAR.
AND LIKE YOU SAID, WE'RE GOING
TO HEAR THAT SO MANY MORE TIMES
OVER THE NEXT FEW DAYS.
>> EMILIE PARKER, ONLY ONE OF 20
KIDS.
>> APRIL OF 2006 SHE WAS BORN.
>> HARD TO BELIEVE.
SANJAY, STAND BY.
SANJAY IS GOING TO BE WITH US.
WE'RE GOING TO CONTINUE OUR
SPECIAL COVERAGE HERE FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT RIGHT AFTER
THIS.
AMERICANS BELIEVE THEY SHOULD BE
IN CHARGE OF THEIR OWN FUTURE.
HOW THEY'LL LIVE TOMORROW.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
MANY HOT DOGS
ARE WITHIN YOU.
TRY PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO,
IT'S THE POWER OF PEPTO,
BUT IT FITS IN YOUR POCKET.
NOW TELL THE WORLD
DANIEL...
OF PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO.
>>> AMIDST THE TRAGEDY HERE AT
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WE'RE
LEARNING AN INCREDIBLE STORY OF
SURVIVAL.
KATE BALLOT WIN IS HERE IN
NEWTOWN, AS WELL.
SHE SPOKE WITH THE FAMILY OF A
VERY BRAVE 6-YEAR-OLD.
KATE, THIS IS AN AMAZING STORY.
I WANT YOU TO SHARE IT WITH ALL
OF OUR VIEWERS.
>> Reporter: A VERY BRAVE
6-YEAR-OLD BOY.
I SAT DOWN WITH ROBERT AND DIANE
LACOTTA.
THEY HAVE TWO CHILDREN AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY, A SECOND GRADER
AND FIRST GRADER.
THEIR 6-YEAR-OLD SON AIDEN WAS
IN VICKI SOTO'S FIRST GRADE
CLASS.
WE NOW KNOW SHE IS ONE OF THE
VICTIMS OF THIS TRAGIC SHOOTING
AND WE ARE ALSO TOLD BY AIDEN'S
PARENTS, THIS YOUNG BOY, 6 YEARS
OLD, CAME FACE-TO-FACE WITH THE
KILLER.
>> WHAT HAD HAPPENED IS WHEN I
GOT TO THE SCHOOL AND REALIZED
IT WAS SANDY HOOK, I PULLED DOWN
DICKENSON DRIVE AS FAR AS I
COULD.
I COULDN'T GET ALL THE WAY.
I DROVE OVER THE CURB AND INTO
THE FIREHOUSE PARKING LOT AND I
SAID, "IT'S HERE, IT'S HERE.
THERE'S BEEN A SHOOTING HERE."
AND I SAW THE EMTs WORKING ON A
LITTLE BOY AND I KNEW IT WASN'T
OUR SON, BECAUSE I KNEW FROM THE
CLOTHES.
SO I RAN TO THE SCHOOL AND, YOU
KNOW THE CHAOS IS INDESCRIBABLE.
I MEAN, IT'S LIKE LIVING THROUGH
COLUMBINE.
EVERYTHING YOU'VE SEEN ON TV.
SO AS THE CHILDREN START TO COME
OUT, YOU KNOW, SINGLE-FILE,
CLASS BY CLASS, GROUP BY GROUP,
WHEN YOU SEE THEIR TEACHER -- I
SAW MY DAUGHTER'S TEACHER, AND
SHE WASN'T -- MY DAUGHTER WASN'T
WITH HER TEACHER.
AND I GRABBED HER TEACHER AND I
ASKED HER WHERE SHE WAS AND SHE
SAID SHE DIDN'T KNOW, BECAUSE
SHE WASN'T WITH THE CLASS.
SO THE KIDS START TO COME OUT
AND WHEN I SAW HER, YOU KNOW,
THE SENSE OF RELIEF IS
INCREDIBLE, BUT IT'S REALLY
SHORT-LIVED BECAUSE I STILL HAVE
ONE IN THERE.
AND I'M WAITING FOR HIM TO COME.
AND HE DIDN'T COME OUT.
AND I DIDN'T SEE HIS TEACHER AND
I DIDN'T SEE HIS CLASSMATES.
AND SO AS A PARENT, YOU KNOW, I
HUGGED MY DAUGHTER AND I SAID,
YOU KNOW -- I TOLD HER TO HUG
HER FRIEND WHO WAS IN HER CLASS
AND I SAID GO TO THE FIRE
STATION, DADDY IS COMING.
AND I'M GOING TO WAIT FOR AIDEN.
I'M GOING TO WAIT.
AND HE DIDN'T COME OUT.
SO YOU KNOW, WHEN YOU'RE
STANDING THERE WAITING, AND NO
ONE WILL TELL YOU ANYTHING, IT'S
INDESCRIBABLE FEELING OF
HELPLESSNESS.
YOU KNOW, WE ARE VERY LUCKY,
BECAUSE I THINK I WAS THERE AN
HOUR, AND THEN THE GROUP STOPPED
COMING.
AND I JUST KNEW NO ONE ELSE WAS
COMING OUT OF THAT SCHOOL.
I JUST KNEW IN MY HEART.
AND I ACTUALLY RECEIVED A TEXT
FROM A FRIEND THAT SAID THAT HE
WAS AT THE POLICE STATION AND HE
WAS SAFE THERE AND ONE OF THE
GROUPS OF KIDS THAT RAN AND GOT
OUT.
AND HAD BEEN PICKED UP.
AND SO WHEN WE WENT THERE AND I
SAW HIM FOR THE FIRST TIME, IT
WAS JUST AN INCREDIBLE FEELING
OF RELIEF.
AND I FEEL SO BLESSED.
IT'S JUST A FEELING OF BLESSING.
>> A MIRACLE.
>> IT TRULY IS.
>> THE CHILDREN WHO GOT OUT OF
THAT CLASSROOM, IT WAS A
BLESSING.
INDESCRIBABLE.
>> IT'S AN AMAZING FEELING.
AND YOU FEEL SO RELIEVED.
BUT AT THE SAME TIME, YOU KNOW
THAT OTHERS CAN'T SHARE THAT
FEELING.
AND YOU JUST -- YOUR HEART
DOESN'T KNOW WHICH DIRECTION TO
GO.
THEIR FRIENDS, THEIR NEIGHBORS.
>> IT WAS ALL SO -- THE
MAGNITUDE OF WHAT'S HAPPENED,
NOT JUST FOR US, BUT FOR
EVERYONE IN THIS COMMUNITY
HASN'T EVEN BEEN FELT YET.
BECAUSE THE CHILDREN EVENTUALLY
WILL LEARN ABOUT THEIR FRIENDS
AND THEIR TEACHER AND OTHERS
THAT THEY KNOW.
AND, YOU KNOW, WE -- WE PARENTS
NEED TO DO THE BEST TO PREPARE
OUR CHILDREN FOR THAT AND
EXPLAIN IN THE BEST WAY WE CAN
THAT MAKES SENSE TO THEM WHAT'S
HAPPENED AND HOW TO KIND OF HELP
THEM THROUGH THAT PROCESS.
>> FROM WHAT YOU'VE BEEN TOLD BY
YOUR SON AND WHAT YOU KNOW NOW,
WHAT HAPPENED?
>> ACCORDING TO AIDEN, THEY WENT
THROUGH THEIR NORMAL DAY.
THEY DID THEIR CIRCLE TIME,
THEIR -- WHERE THEY INTRODUCE
EACH OTHER.
THEY DID THEIR MESSAGE.
>> OVER THE LOUD SPEAKER.
>> AND THEY WERE DOING THEIR
ANNOUNCEMENT OVER THE LOUD
SPEAKER.
AND THAT'S WHEN THEY HEARD
NOISES THAT HE DESCRIBED AS --
INITIALLY THEY THOUGHT WERE
HAMMERS FALLING.
THEN THEY REALIZED THAT IT WAS
GUNSHOTS.
AND MS. SOTO, WHO IS AIDEN'S
TEACHER, HAD THE PRESENCE OF
MIND TO MOVE ALL OF THE CHILDREN
TO A DISTANCE AWAY FROM THE DOOR
ON THE SIDE OF THE ROOM FURTHEST
AWAY FROM THE DOOR.
AND THAT'S WHEN THE GUNMAN BURST
IN, DID NOT SAY A WORD.
NO FACIAL EXPRESSIONS.
AND PROCEEDED TO SHOOT THEIR
TEACHER.
AT THAT TIME, THE CHILDREN FROM
AN EARLY AGE ARE TAUGHT, WHEN
THEY SEE A PERSON WITH A GUN,
YOU RUN AND YOU CALL 911.
AND THAT'S -- THEY PRACTICE IT
IN SCHOOL WITH THEIR FIRE
EMERGENCY DRILLS AND EVERYTHING.
AND WE'RE VERY LUCKY THAT ALL
THE CHILDREN -- MY SON INCLUDED,
HAD THE PRESENCE OF MIND TO
REACT PRESENCE OF MIND TO
REACT APPROPRIATELY.
AND THEY BASICALLY RAN RIGHT
NEXT TO THE GUY OUT THE DOOR.
>> THEY RAN PAST THE MAN?
>> WELL, WE'RE CLEARLY HAVING
SOME TECHNICAL DIFFICULTIES.
AND WE'LL BRING MORE OF MY
INTERVIEW WITH ROBERT AND DIANE,
BUT YOU CAN JUST SEE KIND OF THE
PROCESS THAT THESE FAMILIES WENT
THROUGH, AS THEY LEARNED OF
THIS -- SOMETHING WAS WRONG AT
THIS SCHOOL.
AND THEN AS THEY RUN TO FIND
THEIR CHILDREN, AND IT WAS
REALLY DIFFICULT TO HEAR THEM
RE-PLAY IT.
AND THE PART RIGHT THERE, WOLF,
THAT I THINK IS REALLY IMPORTANT
TO TELL OUR VIEWERS, AS THEIR
SON SAW THIS SHOOTER SHOOT HIS
TEACHER, HE SOMEHOW HAD THE
PRESENCE OF MIND, WELL, FOR HE
AND SEVERAL OF HIS CLASSMATES, A
SIX-YEAR-OLD BOY TO RUN PAST THE
SHOOTER AND RUN OUT OF THE
SCHOOL.
AND EVENTUALLY RUN TO SAFETY.
IT TRULY IS A MIRACLE, THEY SAY,
THEY SAY ANGELS WERE IN THAT
CLASSROOM TO GET THEIR SON OUT
YESTERDAY MORNING.
BUT THEY KNOW THATO MANY
FAMILIES ARE NOT AS LUCKY AS
THEY WERE.
AND THEY SHARE IN THAT GRIEF.
AND THAT IS WHY THEY REALLY
WANTED TO SIT DOWN WITH ME THIS
MORNING.
BECAUSE THEY WANTED TO NOT ONLY
TALK ABOUT HOW BLESSED THEY ARE,
BUT TO ALSO SEND THEIR
CONDOLENCES, AND SHARE THAT
THERE IS A LOT OF HEALING AND
GRIEVING THAT STILL NEEDS TO GO
ON IN THIS TOWN.
>> THEY WANTED TO SHARE THEIR
STORY, THEY WANTED TO SHARE WHAT
WAS GOING ON WITH ALL OF US, AND
LET US KNOW WHAT EXACTLY
HAPPENED.
BECAUSE IT WAS SO IMPORTANT TO
THEM.
IT WAS NOT A SITUATION WHERE YOU
HAD TO COAX THEM OR CONVINCE
THEM OR TALK THEM INTO THIS.
THIS WAS THEIR IDEA.
>> Reporter: THEY'RE A GREAT
FAMILY, AND THEY'RE VERY
PROTECTIVE OF THEIR CHILDREN.
AND THEY DID NOT WANT THEIR
CHILDREN INTERVIEWED.
AND OF COURSE, WE RESPECTED
THAT.
I DID HAVE A CHANCE TO MEET
THEIR CHILDREN AND KIND OF
ACTUALLY PLAY A LITTLE BIT WITH
AIDEN THIS MORNING.
HE IS A REMARKABLE YOUNG BOY.
AND THESE ARE TWO VERY STRONG
PARENTS, THEY ACKNOWLEDGE TO ME
THEY HAVE A VERY ROUGH ROAD
AHEAD, EVEN FOR THEIR FAMILY, TO
FIGURE OUT HOW THEY, AS PARENTS,
AND AS HUMAN BEINGS WILL LEARN
HOW TO DEAL WITH THIS TRAGEDY.
BECAUSE THEY -- THEY SAY THEY
DON'T KNOW, YOU KNOW, NO ONE IS
PREPARED FOR THIS TYPE OF THING,
WOLF, THAT IS THE UNDERSTATEMENT
OF THE YEAR, WOLF.
>> WE'RE GOING TO HAVE MORE OF
YOUR INTERVIEW, KATE, COMING UP
LATER IN OUR SPECIAL SATURDAY
SITUATION ROOM.
MEANWHILE, OUR SPECIAL COVERAGE
WILL RESUME RIGHT AFTER THIS.
>>> WE'RE HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE GETTING MORE REACTION, THE
INCREDIBLE FALLOUT FROM THIS
HORRIBLE, HORRIBLE TRAGEDY THAT
OCCURRED HERE YESTERDAY IN THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, 26 PEOPLE
WERE SHOT.
SIX OF THEM ADULTS.
20 CHILDREN, AND WE NOW HAVE THE
NAMES OF EVERYONE WHO WAS
KILLED.
SANJAY GUPTA IS WATCHING AND
LISTENING AND WONDERING WHAT IS
GOING ON, LIKE ALL OF US,
SANJAY, AT THE TOP OF THE HOUR,
NEAR THE TOP OF THE HOUR WE'RE
GOING TO BE HEARING FROM THE
BROTHER OF NANCY LANZA, SHE IS
THE MOTHER OF TWENTY-YEAR-OLD
ADAM LANZA.
THE BROTHER WANTS TO SPEAK OUT,
WE'RE GOING TO HEAR WHAT HE HAS
TO SAY.
ANOTHER POWERFUL PERSPECTIVE
FROM A PERSON FROM THE LANZA
FAMILY.
>> OBVIOUSLY, YES, WE HAVEN'T
HEARD FROM THEM AT ALL.
AND PEOPLE KEEP ASKING THIS
QUESTION, WHY.
AND I DON'T KNOW THAT HE CAN
PROVIDE AN ANSWER.
AND AS YOU AND I TALKED ABOUT
EARLIER, I'M NOT SURE IT IS EVEN
KNOWABLE.
A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE CURIOUS TO
HEAR FROM HIM, AS WELL, AND TRY
TO FIGURE OUT IF THERE IS
ANYMORE SORT OF SENSE OF ALL OF
THIS.
>> AND YOU'RE A NEUROSURGEON,
YOU STUDY THE BRAIN.
AND I DON'T KNOW IF YOU CAN MAKE
ANY SENSE OF WHAT TRIGGERS
SOMEBODY TO GO INTO A SCHOOL
LIKE THAT AND JUST START KILLING
YOUNG KIDS.
>> I CAN'T, YOU KNOW, AND I
THINK YOU KNOW THAT THERE WILL
BE A LOT OF DISCUSSION ABOUT
THIS, I THINK, IN TERMS OF
LOOKING AT POSSIBLE CAUSES, EVEN
MEDICAL CAUSES.
WHETHER IT BE MENTAL ILLNESS OR
SOMETHING, BUT IT IS JUST SO
HARD TO SAY, WOLF, AND WE HAVE
COVERED SO MANY TRAGEDIES LIKE
THIS.
AND I THINK IT IS DISTINCTLY
UNSATISFYING, BECAUSE I THINK
THAT NOW PEOPLE EXPECT THAT
THERE IS GOING TO BE SOME
ABSOLUTE ANSWER TO WHAT HAS
HAPPENED HERE.
AND I JUST DON'T THINK THAT
THERE IS.
AND EVEN AS A MEDICAL SCIENTIST,
WE'RE SO USED TO SAYING HERE IS
THAT BLOCKAGE, LET'S HOPE THAT
UP.
OR HERE IS HOW THIS NEEDS TO BE
TREATED.
AND WE JUST DON'T HAVE THAT IN
CERTAIN SITUATIONS LIKE THIS.
>> BECAUSE I ASSUME THEY WILL DO
AN AUTOPSY ON ADAM, AND TAKE A
LOOK.
IF YOU WERE INVOLVED, WHAT WOULD
YOU LOOK FOR?
YOU'RE A NEUROSURGEON.
>> WELL, YOU WOULD WANT TO SEE
IF THERE WAS SOMETHING OBVIOUS
IN THE BRAIN, ORGANIC IN THE
BRAIN, THEY'RE GOING TO LOOK IN
TERMS OF HOW HE DIED,
SPECIFICALLY --
>> WELL, HE TOOK HIS OWN LIFE.
>> HE TOOK HIS OWN LIFE.
THEY WILL LOOK FOR THAT, AS
WELL.
BUT IT IS UNLIKELY, WOULD BE MY
GUESS, THAT THEY CAN SAY THIS IS
AN EXPLANATION IN SOME WAY, OF
ALL OF THIS.
>> LIKE A PHYSICAL EXPLANATION.
>> YEAH, WHETHER THERE WAS
SOMETHING INHIBITING JUDGMENT OR
WHETHER IT WOULD CAUSE SOMETHING
LIKE THAT.
BUT EVEN IF YOU DID FIND
SOMETHING LIKE THAT TO TAKE AN
ORGANIC THING, AND TO SAY
TRANSLATE THAT TO A SORT OF
BEHAVIORAL THING, IT IS JUST
HARD, WOLF.
>> YOU WERE OVER AT ONE OF THE
CRISIS CENTERS THAT WAS
ESTABLISHED HERE, TALKING TO
SOME OF THE MEDICAL
PROFESSIONALS.
>> I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT TO EXPECT,
WOLF, I HAVE TO BE HONEST.
BECAUSE THIS IS A TOWN THAT I