WHEN WE DO LEAVE THIS TOWN AND
WHEN OUR WORLD CONTINUES, WE
LEAVE ALL THESE PEOPLE WITH A
BRAND-NEW NORMAL.
AND SOMETHING THAT THEY'RE GOING
TO HAVE TO FIGURE OUT FOR
THEMSELVES.
WHAT THEIR NEW NORMAL IS GOING
TO BE LIKE.
>> THE TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN HAS
MANY PEOPLE WONDERING HOW THEY
CAN HELP THOSE WHO ARE IMPACTED.
SO WE PUT A LIST TOGETHER OF
CHARITABLE ORGANIZATIONS ON OUR
WEBSITE.
JUST VISIT CNN.COM/IMPACT.
YOU CAN HELP.
"CNN NEWSROOM" CONTINUES RIGHT
NOW WITH DON LEMON IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
DON?
>>> HI, EVERYONE.
I'M BROOKE BALDWIN LIVE AT THE
CNN WORLD HEADQUARTERS IN
ATLANTA.
DON LEMON IS STANDING BY IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WHERE
WE'LL CHECK IN WITH HIM HERE
MOMENTARILY.
BUT THE STORY THIS WEEK, IT JUST
BREAKS YOUR HEART TO SEE THERE,
THESE FUNERALS GOING ON FOR
THESE ITTY-BITTY CHILDREN HERE,
TWO MORE YOUNG VICTIMS BEING
LAID TO REST TODAY.
SERVICES FOR 6-YEAR-OLD JESSICA
REKOS WERE HELD AT ST. ROSE OF
LIMA CATHOLIC CHURCH THERE IN
TOWN.
AS HER RELATIVES GRIEVE, THEY
ARE ALSO TRYING TO HELP HER
BROTHER TRAVIS UNDERSTAND WHY HE
CAN'T PLAY WITH HIS BEST FRIEND.
HE WANTS TO KNOW WHERE IS HIS
BEST FRIEND.
WE FOUND OUT JESSICA LOVED
HORSES.
SHE LOVED WATCHING HORSE MOVIES,
DRAWING HORSES.
APPARENTLY SHE ASKED SANTA CLAUS
THIS CHRISTMAS FOR A NEW PAIR OF
COW GIRL BOOTS.
ALSO TODAY, 6-YEAR-OLD JAMES
MATTIOLI WAS BURIED.
THE FUNERAL HELD AT ST. ROSE OF
LIMA CHURCH THERE IN NEWTOWN.
THE FAMILY POSTED A PUBLIC
OBITUARY.
THEY CALLED HIM, QUOTE, OUR
BELOVED PRINCE.
THEY SAY JAMES LOVED SCHOOL AND
SPENT HOURS AND HOURS PLAYING
HOCKEY.
STUDENTS IN NEWTOWN, THEY ARE
BACK IN SCHOOL TODAY.
BUT TO BE CLEAR, NOT THE
STUDENTS OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
STUDENTS AT OTHER SCHOOLS, THEY
ARE SEEING MORE POLICE, MORE
COUNSELORS ON HAND, JUST BEING
IN TOWN THE LAST COUPLE OF DAYS
THERE ARE A LOT OF POLICE
OFFICERS JUST SITTING IN THE
DRIVEWAYS OF A LOT OF THE
SCHOOLS HERE, CLEARLY SECURITY
BEING BEEFED UP IN THIS TOWN
RIGHT NOW.
TEACHERS UNION SAYS CLASSES WILL
DISCUSS THE SHOOTING IN AGE
APPROPRIATE MANNER.
IT IS NOT CLEAR YET, THOUGH,
WHEN SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL WILL RESUME CLASS.
BUT WHEN THEY DO, IT WILL
CERTAINLY BE AT A DIFFERENT
SCHOOL IN THE NEIGHBORING TOWN
OF MONROE.
AND I JUST GOT BACK FROM NEWTOWN
THIS MORNING, AND DURING DINNER
TIME LAST NIGHT, I WAS INVITED
TO SPEND SOME TIME WITH THESE
TWO VOLUNTEER FIREFIGHTERS,
THEY'RE WITH NEWTOWN HOOK AND
LADDER AND THEY WENT INTO
EMERGENCY MODE, OF COURSE, EARLY
LAST FRIDAY MORNING.
THEY ARE ROB MANA AND RAY CORBO.
THEY SERVED THEIR COMMUNITY NOW
FOR MORE THAN 20 YEARS EACH.
BUT THE DAY THEY GOT THAT CALL,
THEY SAY IT WAS LIKE NOTHING
THEY HAD EVER SEEN BEFORE.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU ALL BEEN
VOLUNTEERING AS FIREFIGHTERS?
>> ABOUT 21 YEARS.
>> A LITTLE OVER 25.
>> AND WHERE WERE YOU FRIDAY?
>> I WAS WORKING PROBABLY ABOUT
2,000 FEET FROM THE SCHOOL, ON A
STONE WALL IN BUSINESS DISTRICT
IN THE CENTER OF SANDY HOOK.
SO MY RESPONSE TIME WAS VERY
QUICK.
I WAS THERE VERY SOON.
>> SO YOU WERE THERE.
>> MM-HMM.
>> DID YOU HAVE ANY IDEA WHAT
YOU WERE WALKING INTO?
>> NO.
>> NOT AT ALL.
MATTER OF FACT, WE WERE JUST
TALKING ABOUT THAT.
WE HAD A FIRE CALL A FEW MINUTES
AGO AND WE WERE TALKING ABOUT
THAT ON THE WAY BACK.
AND YOU GET THE INITIAL DISPATCH
AND YOU REALLY DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE COMING INTO, BUT FOR THE
MOST PART YOU'RE READY FOR IT.
AND THIS TIME THAT'S NOT THE
CASE.
>> YOU'RE NEVER READY FOR THIS.
>> NEVER.
I DON'T THINK ANYBODY -- ANYBODY
ANYWHERE, IF THEY TELL YOU THEY
WERE READY FOR SOMETHING LIKE
THIS, THEY'RE NOT BEING HONEST
WITH YOU.
>> I DON'T WANT TO GET INTO
SPECIFICS, BUT HELP US
UNDERSTAND, IN THE SCHOOL, WERE
PEOPLE PANICKED, WERE THEY
SCREAMING, WERE THEY RUNNING?
WHAT DID YOU SEE?
>> IT WAS VERY CHAOTIC AND VERY
EMOTIONAL, PROBABLY THE BEST WAY
TO DESCRIBE IT.
>> KIDS EMOTIONAL, TEACHERS
EMOTIONAL.
>> EVERYBODY WAS EMOTIONAL.
>> WHAT WERE THEY SAYING.
>> LAW ENFORCEMENT WAS PRETTY
EMOTIONAL.
IT WAS EVERYBODY.
THIS IS AKE EAFFECTED EVERY SIN
PERSON THAT WAS THERE,
IMMEDIATELY.
I SHOULDN'T SAY IMMEDIATELY.
VERY EARLY ON.
IT WAS DETERMINED THAT THIS WAS
BAD, REALLY, REALLY BAD.
>> AND I ALSO ASKED THESE TWO
MEN ABOUT ONE MOMENT OVER THE
LAST HOWEVER MANY HOURS THAT
REALLY SEARED INTO THEIR
MEMORIES AND THEY TOLD ME, AS
MANY PEOPLE DID, IT WAS THE
PARENTS, THE PARENTS FRIDAY
MORNING, THE PARENTS WAITING FOR
THEIR CHILDREN, THE CHILDREN WHO
WOULD NEVER COME HOME.
>> AS THE CHILDREN WERE COMING
DOWN THE STREET, YOU KNOW,
LITTLE BY LITTLE, CLASSROOM BY
CLASSROOM, HOWEVER THEY WERE
DOING IT, YOU KNOW, ALL HOLDING
HANDS, PARENTS WERE CLAIMING
THEIR CHILDREN.
AFTER A LITTLE WHILE, ONCE THEY
CLAIMED THEIR KID, SIGNED THEM
OUT, I'M NOT SURE HOW THEY
WORKED IT, BUT THEY LEFT, THE
ONES THAT DIDN'T, YOU KNOW, YOU
NOTICED THERE IS SOME THAT ARE
STILL STICKING AROUND.
AND THAT'S WHEN YOU REALIZE THAT
THEY'RE PROBABLY NOT GOING TO BE
LEAVING.
THEY'RE GOING TO GET THE
CONFIRMATION SOON ENOUGH THAT,
YOU KNOW, THEY'RE NOT GOING TO
BE GRABBING THEIR CHILD AND
HUGGING THEM AND TAKING THEM
HOME.
THEIR LIFE IS CHANGED FOREVER.
>> YOU REALIZED THAT IN THAT
MOMENT?
>> YEAH.
THAT WAS SOMETHING THAT, LIKE I
SAID, A COUPLE OF TIMES WE HAD
TO GO BACK DOWN TO THAT STAGING
AREA AND, YOU KNOW, YOU LOOK
AROUND AND YOU MAKE SURE THERE
IS NOBODY ELSE IN DISTRESS THAT
MIGHT NEED OUR ASSISTANCE, AND
YOU NOTICE THIS -- PARENTS BEEN
RIGHT THERE IN THE FRONT OF THE
LINE FOR TWO HOURS NOW, AND
THERE IS NO MORE KIDS AROUND TO
TAKE HOME AND, YOU KNOW, YOU
KNOW THIS IS BAD, THEY'RE NOT --
THEY'RE GOING TO GET SOME BAD
NEWS.
AND I'M SURE THAT THEY AT THAT
POINT KNEW IT, BUT THERE IS THAT
SHRED OF HOPE THERE IS SOMEBODY
HIDING IN A CLOSET OR, YOU KNOW,
THEY MISSED, BUT ULTIMATELY THAT
WASN'T THE CASE FOR ANY OF THEM.
>> AND, YOU KNOW, AS IT WAS
TOUGH FOR THEM TO RECALL THOSE
MOMENTS, I DO JUST WANT TO LET
YOU KNOW, WE HAD A LIGHTER
MOMENT AT THE BEGINNING OF THE
INTERVIEW WHEN THEY TALKED TO ME
ABOUT SOMETHING THAT IS PUTTING
A SMILE ON A LOT OF KIDS' FACES
IN NEWTOWN THIS WEEK.
TEDDY BEARS BY THE TRUCK LOADS,
THEY TOLD ME.
NOT JUST BY THE GARBAGE BAG
LOAD, THE TRUCK LOAD, SENT TO
THEM FROM FIRE AND EMS CREWS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY FROM THEM TO
HELP OUT IN NEWTOWN.
YOU'LL HEAR ROB AND RAY TALK TO
ME ABOUT THAT AND HOW THAT'S
HELPING THEM HEAL.
THAT'S NEXT HOUR.
AND I KNOW A LOT OF YOU ARE
REACHING OUT TO US AND ASKING
HOW YOU CAN HELP THE PEOPLE
AFFECTED IN THIS SWEET SLEEPY
COMMUNITY IN CONNECTICUT.
AND YOU CAN.
SO WE HAVE PUT A LIST OF
CHARITABLE ORGANIZATIONS ON OUR
WEBSITE.
JUST GO TO CNN.COM/IMPACT.
CNN.COM/IMPACT FOR MORE ON THAT.
>>> WE ARE GETTING NEW
INFORMATION HERE ON THE DETAILS
OF THIS INVESTIGATION UNRAVELING
AS FAR AS THIS COMPUTER THAT THE
SHOOTER APPARENTLY SMASHED IN
HIS HOME BEFORE GOING OUT ON
THIS GRIM RAMPAGE ON FRIDAY
MORNING.
DEB FEYERICK IS LIVE FOR US
THERE IN NEWTOWN WITH MORE ON
THAT.
DEB, WHAT ARE YOU LEARNING?
>> Reporter: WELL, BROOKE, WE
CAN TELL YOU INVESTIGATORS WERE
HERE AT THE HOME FOR ABOUT AN
HOUR OR SO THIS AFTERNOON.
THEY PULLED OUT JUST A LITTLE
WHILE AGO.
THEY HAVE BEEN RETURNING TO THE
HOUSE PERIODICALLY AS THEY GET
NEW LEADS AND AS THEY GET WIND
OF NEW DEVELOPMENTS.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT EXACTLY THOSE
ARE.
WE CAN TELL YOU WE HAVE
CONFIRMED WITH THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER THAT IN FACT TOXICOLOGY
TESTS WERE PERFORMED ON ADAM
LANZA.
THOSE TOXICOLOGY REPORTS
EXPECTED BACK IN ABOUT TWO WEEKS
AND AT THAT POINT, THE DOCTORS
WILL KNOW BETTER WHETHER HE HAD
ANY SORT OF DRUGS IN HIS SYSTEM.
AND WHAT THOSE DRUGS MAY HAVE
BEEN.
WHETHER HE MAY HAVE BEEN TAKING
ANY SORT OF DRUGS FOR
PSYCHOLOGICAL PROBLEMS, OR ANY
ILLEGAL MEDICATIONS AS WELL.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER WAS TOLD BY
INVESTIGATORS THAT LANZA HAD
ASPERGER'S SYNDROME AND THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER IS TRYING TO
REALLY RUN THAT TO THE GROUND TO
SEE WHETHER IN FACT THERE WAS
SOMETHING ELSE THAT MAY HAVE
BEEN GOING ON, SOME OTHER
PSYCHIATRIC PROBLEM THAT MAY
HAVE CAUSED THIS VIOLENT SPREE.
THE BODIES OF ADAM LANZA AND HIS
MOTHER BOTH OF THEM AUTOPSIES
WERE COMPLETED ON THAT.
THE AUTOPSY REPORTS SHOWING THAT
NANCY LANZA WAS SHOT HERE, IN
HER HOME, AS SHE SLEPT, IN HER
BED, FOUR TIMES IN THE HEAD.
AND THEN IT APPEARS THAT ADAM
LANZA TRIED TO DESTROY HIS
COMPUTER, DESTROY THE EVIDENCE,
THE COMPUTER THAT INVESTIGATORS
FOUND WAS SMASHED INTO PIECES.
THE HARD DRIVE BADLY DAMAGED
ACCORDING TO A LAW ENFORCEMENT
SOURCE.
AND THEY'RE HAVING TROUBLE
TRYING TO RETRIEVE SOME OF THE
INFORMATION OFF OF THAT.
ALMOST AS IF ADAM LANZA WAS
TRYING TO ERASE HIS STEPS
LEADING UP TO THIS CRIME.
NOW, ALSO, WE'RE TOLD THE
AUTOPSY SHOWED THAT AFTER THE
HORRIBLE SPREE AT THE SCHOOL,
ADAM LANZA TOOK HIS OWN LIFE, A
SINGLE GUNSHOT WOUND ALSO TO THE
HEAD.
WHAT IS SO INTERESTING ABOUT ALL
OF THIS IS THAT THE MOTHER,
NANCY LANZA, WAS IN CHARGE OF
ANY UNREIMBURSED PSYCHIATRIC OR
PSYCHOLOGICAL COMPETENCES FOR
HER SON.
SO, AGAIN, ANOTHER INDICATION
THAT THERE WAS SOMETHING MORE
GOING ON, THAT SHE WAS THE ONE
WHO WAS REALLY TRYING TO MANAGE
WHATEVER IT WAS HE WAS WRESTLING
WITH, THE DEMONS HE WAS -- HE
APPEARED TO BE STRUGGLING WITH
OVER THE COURSE OF THE LAST
THREE YEARS.
AND, YOU KNOW, BROOKE WHAT IS SO
ASTONISHING TO ME HAVING COVERED
A NUMBER OF TRAGEDIES, TERRIBLE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS, IS THAT
ADAM LANZA, THE LAST THREE YEARS
OF HIS LIFE, THEY'RE BASICALLY A
MYSTERY TO ALMOST EVERYBODY.
HE SEEMS TO HAVE DISAPPEARED
AFTER COURSES HE TOOK IN 2009 AT
A LOCAL UNIVERSITY, BUT AFTER
THAT, VERY LITTLE IS KNOWN.
THE MOTHER WAS TRYING TO
MAINSTREAM HIM, MOVING HIM FROM
SCHOOL TO SCHOOL, BUT THE LAST
THREE YEARS, THEY REALLY --
THERE IS JUST -- THERE IS SO
LITTLE INFORMATION.
IT IS REALLY LIKE ANY -- IT IS
UNLIKE ANY OTHER SORT OF
SHOOTING, SHOOTING, TRAGEDY THAT
I'VE REPORTED ON.
>> IT IS SO BIZARRE HE'S SUCH A
MYSTERY OVER THE LAST COUPLE OF
YEARS.
AND TALKING TO PEOPLE IN AND
AROUND TOWN, SO MANY PEOPLE SO
BADLY WANT TO UNDERSTAND IF
THERE IS ANY KIND OF CONNECTION
BETWEEN THE SHOOTER AND THE
SCHOOL.
AND SO FAR, YOU KNOW, SO FAR AS
YOU'RE SAYING, NOTHING.
I KNOW INVESTIGATORS ARE WORKING
HARD.
DEBORAH FEYERICK, THANK YOU SO
MUCH.
WE JUST HAVE NOW --
>> THE ONE THING --
>> DEB, GO AHEAD.
JUMP BACK IN.
>> THE ONE QUICK THING WE WANT
TO CLARIFY, AGAIN, THIS IS ALSO
WHAT IS SO FASCINATING, YOU
WOULD THINK IT WOULD BE AS EASY
AS GOING TO THE SCHOOL RECORDS
AND SAYING, YES, OF COURSE HE
WAS HERE, THE SCHOOL HAS NOT
BEEN ABLE TO CONFIRM THAT,
OFFICIALS HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE TO
CONFIRM IT.
A WOMAN WE SPOKE TO HERE IN TOWN
SAYS HER DAUGHTER AND ADAM LANZA
WERE CLASSMATES AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY IN THE FIRST AND
THIRD GRADES.
SO EVEN THAT IS SORT OF THIS --
SORT OF LITTLE MYSTERY WE CAN'T
KIND OF CHECK OFF TO KNOW WHY HE
TARGETED THAT SCHOOL.
WE CAN TELL YOU, THIS IS KIND OF
IMPORTANT, A LITTLE BIT SAD,
THIS MORNING, YOU KNOW, FROM
THIS HOUSE, HERE IS THE HOUSE,
SCHOOL BUSES KEPT PASSING THIS
HOUSE, THEY WERE PICKING UP
CHILDREN AND WE DO KNOW, BROOKE,
THAT AT LEAST TWO OF THE
CHILDREN WHO DIED, THEY LIVE
REALLY WITHIN -- LESS THAN HALF
A MILE FROM THE HOUSE.
THOSE SCHOOL BUSES, THOSE
CHILDREN THAT WERE VERY MUCH
PART OF THIS NEIGHBORHOOD, WEHEE
ADAM LANZA WAS LIVING --
>> PASSING BY THE CRIME SCENE
TAPE, HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN?
TOUGH FOR PARENTS RIGHT NOW.
DEB FEYERICK, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
>>> THIS NEWS JUST IN TO US AT
CNN, TALKING ABOUT THE STUDENTS
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE'RE NOW LEARNING HERE FROM THE
SUPERINTENDENT OF SCHOOLS THAT
THESE LITTLE KIDS WILL NOT BE
GOING BACK TO CLASS UNTIL AFTER
THE HOLIDAYS.
PEOPLE ARE WONDERING IF IT WOULD
BE BEFORE OR AFTER, AFTER THE
HOLIDAY BREAK.
LET ME QUOTE PART OF THIS
LETTER.
THE SUPERINTENDENT THERE IN
NEWTOWN SAYS, QUOTE, WE NEED TO
TEND TO OUR TEACHERS AND
STUDENTS NEED TO FEEL
COMFORTABLE AFTER THIS TRAUMA IN
THIS NEW PLACE.
SHE GOES ON TO SAY, QUOTE,
TEACHERS MAY BE CALLING YOU TO
INVITE YOU TO VISIT CHALK HILL
WITH YOUR CHILD THIS WEEK, TO
WALK AROUND, AND SEE THE
CLASSROOM AND GET FAMILIAR WITH
THIS NEW SANDY HOOK HOME.
THAT'S WHERE THEY'LL BE HEADED,
OF COURSE, AFTER HOLIDAY BREAK.
TOUGH TIME FOR SO MANY PEOPLE
THERE IN THIS TOWN.
AND WITH JUST TWO WEEKS LEFT
HERE, TOTALLY SWITCHING GEARS,
WE'LL TAKE YOU BACK TO NEWTOWN,
LIVE, IN A MOMENT.
>>> BUT WITH TWO WEEKS LEFT
BEFORE THE FISCAL CLIFF
DEADLINE, JOHN BOEHNER HAS COME
UP WITH A PLAN B.
DETAILS ON THAT PLAN NEXT.
QUESTIONS?
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
♪
BECOMING
PART OF THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
TREES WILL TALK TO NETWORKS
WILL TALK TO SCIENTISTS
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE.
CARS WILL TALK TO ROAD SENSORS
WILL TALK TO STOPLIGHTS
ABOUT TRAFFIC EFFICIENCY.
THE AMBULANCE WILL TALK
TO PATIENT RECORDS
WILL TALK TO DOCTORS
ABOUT SAVING LIVES.
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
THE NEXT BIG THING?
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
♪
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
♪
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
>>> 14 DAYS NOW.
14 DAYS UNTIL WE HIT THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
WE HAVE A FRIEND FREENZY OF MOV
WASHINGTON.
LET ME JUST DO A QUICK RESET
HERE SO WE CAN ALL UNDERSTAND
WHERE WE STAND.
SO THIS TIME YESTERDAY WE WERE
REPORTING A MAJOR CONCESSION ON
THE PART OF HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER.
HIS VERY FIRST OFFER OF HIGHER
TAX RATES, HIGHER RATES FOR
ANYONE MAKING MORE THAN A
MILLION BUCKS A YEAR.
WELL, QUICK AS A WHIP HERE, THE
PRESIDENT GAVE SOME AS WELL.
HE MOVED HIS BAR FOR THE TAX
HIKE FROM INCOMES STARTING AT A
QUARTER MILLION DOLLARS, THAT
WITH A HIS EARLIER STANCE, TO
INCOMES BEGINNING A BIT HIGHER
AT $400,000 A YEAR.
THE PRESIDENT ALSO OFFERING
SIGNIFICANT SPENDING CUTS,
INCLUDING CUTS IN SOCIAL
SECURITY PAYMENTS TO BETTER OFF
SENIORS, PLUS A PROMISE OF
HEALTH SAVINGS FURTHER DOWN THE
ROAD.
I KNOW, I KNOW IT IS A LOT TO
FOLLOW.
BOTTOM LINE, THOUGH, THINGS SEEM
TO BE MOVING ALONG, PERHAPS IN
THE RIGHT DIRECTION.
BUT THEN BOEHNER TOSSED A
CURVEBALL HERE.
FOR THAT, LET'S GO TO SENIOR
CONGRESSIONAL CORRESPONDENT DANA
BASH WHO WILL WALK ME THROUGH
THIS HERE.
LET'S HOLD OFF IF YOU WOULD ON
THE BOEHNER PLAN B.
TELL ME, FIRST, JUST WHAT THE
SPEAKER SAID TODAY ABOUT THE
PRESIDENT'S LATEST OFFER,
BECAUSE A LOT OF DEMOCRATS SEEM
TO THINK THAT THE PRESIDENT GAVE
MORE THAN HE ACTUALLY SHOULD
HAVE.
>> Reporter: OH, ABSOLUTELY.
A LOT OF DEMOCRATS THINK THAT,
PARTICULARLY NOT JUST ON
SPENDING CUTS, BUT THE KIND OF
SPENDING CUTS.
I HEARD FROM DEMOCRATIC SOURCE
THAT THE PRESIDENT'S LIAISON
HERE GOT AN EARFUL FROM
PROGRESSIVE DEMOCRATS IN A
MEETING THIS MORNING FOR GIVING
ON THE WHOLE ISSUE OF -- A
TECHNICAL CHANGE, WHICH WOULD
EFFECTIVELY MAKE PEOPLE'S SOCIAL
SECURITY CHECKS SMALLER.
BUT BOTTOM LINE FROM THE
REPUBLICAN POINT OF VIEW, THEY
SAY, THE SPEAKER TOLD HIS CAUCUS
THIS MORNING, THAT THE PRESIDENT
IS NOT GIVING ENOUGH WHEN IT
COMES TO SPENDING CUTS AND WHEN
IT COMES TO REVENUE.
THAT HE WANTS A VIRTUAL ONE TO
ONE RATIO AND THE WAY THEY DO
THE MATH, THE REPUBLICANS DO THE
MATH, THEY SAY THEY DON'T THINK
THEY'RE GETTING THAT.
THAT'S WHY HE'S PUSHING THIS
PLAN B.
>> SO WALK ME THROUGH PLAN B AND
WHY.
>> Reporter: PLAN B IS THE
SPEAKER WILL TRY TO CRAFT
LEGISLATION THAT THEY HOPE TO
PUT ON THE FLOOR AS SOON AS THIS
THURSDAY, SO IN TWO DAYS, WHICH
WOULD KEEP TAX CUTS WHERE THEY
ARE FOR EVERYBODY MAKING UP TO
$1 MILLION A YEAR.
HOUSEHOLDS MAKING UP TO $1
MILLION A YEAR.
WHY IS HE DOING THAT?
THE REASON IS BECAUSE IT IS A
TACTICAL MOVE.
HE AND THE REPUBLICANS WANT TO
TRY TO PUSH THE PRESIDENT TO
GIVE MORE ON THOSE SPENDING CUT
S, TO GIVE -- TO FORCE THE
REPUBLICANS TO GIVE LESS, SO TO
SPEAK, ON TAX REVENUE.
SO IT IS DEFINITELY A TACTICAL
MOVE.
THE DEMOCRATS ARE LAUGHING IT
OFF, LITERALLY.
I'VE HEARD FROM DEMOCRATIC
SOURCES THAT IT IS MORE OF A
PUNCHLI LINE THAN A COMPROMISE.
IT IS UNCLEAR FILL IS IT
REPUBLICANS CAN GET THE VOTES IN
THE HOUSE AND WE'RE TOLD THAT --
I'M TOLD BY REPUBLICAN SOURCES
THEY'RE GOING TO HAVE YET
ANOTHER MEETING LATER TODAY AT
5:00 EASTERN OF HOUSE
REPUBLICANS TO TRY TO, WHAT THEY
CALL, WHIP THE VOTES TO MAKE
SURE THEY HAVE THE VOTES FOR
THIS THERE IS PROBABLY GOING TO
BE A SERIES OF VOTES ON
THURSDAY, BUT THEY'RE NOT SURE
OF THAT.
YOU TALK ABOUT THE SENATE, WHERE
IT HAS TO GO NEXT, DEMOCRATS WHO
RUN THE SENATE THERE SAY THEY
JUST SIMPLY DON'T THINK IT IS
GOING TO PASS.
WE'RE GOING TO SEE A LOT OF
TO'ing AND FRO'ing AND VOTE
TAKING AND AT THE END OF THE
DAY, FOR POLITICAL REASONS,
NOTHING MORE.
>> SO PUNCH LINE, COMPROMISE.
ONE THING WE CAN AGREE ON, 14
DAYS, 14 DAYS.
QUICKLY, DANA, 30 SECONDS, WHAT
HAPPENS NEXT?
>> Reporter: BOY, YOUR GUESS IS
AS GOOD AS MINE.
I JUST SAW SOMETHING FOR THE
FIRST TIME IN MY E-MAIL THAT
SAID MERRY CLIFFMAS.
>> DON'T LET THAT JOKE BEGIN.
NO!
OKAY.
>> Reporter: IF IT WEREN'T SO
SAD, WE WOULD BE LAUGH, BUT
WE'RE NOT.
>> MERRY CLIFFMAS.
LET'S HAVE A DEAL.
THANKS SO MUCH.
WE'LL CHECK BACK IN WITH YOU.
AS WE MENTIONED, WE'LL CONTINUE
ON WITH THE OTHER STORIES OF THE
DAY.
ALSO CONTINUE FOLLOWING THE
AFTERMATH OF THE HORRENDOUS
SHOOTINGS IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
DON LEMON WILL JOIN ME FROM
NEWTOWN AFTER THIS QUICK BREAK.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] CAMPBELL'S
GREEN BEAN CASSEROLE.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO
>>> AND I'M BROOKE BALDWIN AT
THE CNN WORLD HEADQUARTERS IN
ATLANTA, JOINED BY MY COLLEAGUE
THERE IN NEWTOWN, STILL FLANKED
BY SO MANY PEOPLE THERE IN
NEWTOWN.
IT IS AMAZING, BEING THERE, NOT
ONLY THE PEOPLE FROM WITHIN TOWN
WALKING AROUND AND PLACING THE
TEDDY BEARS AND PETTING THE DOGS
IN TOWN TO MAKE THE KIDS FEEL
BET, PEOPLE ARE COMING FROM
COUNTIES AWAY.
I SAW SOMEWHERE THERE FROM
BRAZIL.
IT IS TREMENDOUS.
>> YEAH.
SOMEONE FROM -- I SAW SOMEONE
FROM ALABAMA AND, YOU KNOW,
BROOKE, THERE IS MEDIA FROM
EVERYWHERE, ALL OVER THE WORLD.
LOOK HOW THIS -- YOU'VE SEEN
THIS MEMORIAL HERE.
LOOK HOW -- IT IS A MAKESHIFT
MEMORIAL THAT SPROUTED UP
SATURDAY.
WHEN YOU AND I FIRST GOT HERE IT
WAS JUST CANDLES, A COUPLE OF
CANDLES AND PEOPLE STARTED
BRINGING MORE, TEDDY BEARS AND
TEDDY BEARS.
COME OVER HERE.
THIS IS WENDY AND PHILIP.
YOU GUYS ARE FROM NEW BRUNSWICK,
NEW JERSEY.
YOU HAVE A BUNCH OF TEDDY BEARS
YOU COLLECTED.
WHO DID YOU COLLECT THEM FROM?
>> MOSTLY FRIENDS.
>> A BOX FULL OF TEDDY BEARS AND
SHE'S GOT A BAG FULL OF TEDDY
BEARS AS WELL AND IN BOTH HANDS
AND THERE ARE SOME TEDDY BEARS
OUT HERE THAT ARE JUST PLAIN AND
NOT COVERED.
SOME LIKE THIS ONE COVERED IN
PLASTIC AS THEY'RE TRYING TO
PRESERVE THEM.
BUT, AGAIN, EVERYONE HAS BEEN
COMING OUT.
I'LL SHOW YOU, EVEN PEOPLE
JUST -- I SHOWED YOU EARLIER ON
SATURDAY NIGHT, WHEN THEY FIRST
GOT HERE, COMFORT DOGS.
THESE DOGS ARE JUST FROM THE
COMMUNITY.
THEY'RE SPENCER'S DOGS.
>> FROM READING.
>> HE CAME FROM READING TO BRING
THEM.
THIS IS MISS BONITA AND MR. BIG.
>> CORRECT.
>> YOU'VE BEEN GIVING THE
CHILDREN RIDES ON THE DOGS.
>> SMILES, RIDES, ANY TYPE OF
LAUGHTER WE CAN BRING TO THEM.
THEY GET A KICK OUT OF IT.
>> WHY DID YOU DO IT?
>> BECAUSE BEING A NEIGHBOR TO
THIS COMMUNITY, YOU FEEL
HELPLESS, YOU GOT TO HELP IN ANY
WAY YOU CAN.
>> WHO'S A GOOD BOY?
THEY'RE SO CUTE AND CUDDLY.
AND THE KIDS GET ON AND RIDE
THEM.
WHAT HAPPENS?
>> THEY JUST LAUGH AND GIGGLE.
>> YEAH.
YEAH.
AND IT IS THE FIRST SMILE.
EVERY TIME -- THE FIRST TIME I
SAW A DOG HERE, THEY WERE THE
FIRST SMILES I SAW ON ANYONE'S
FACES.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
IT STARTS WITH MAKING EYE
CONTACT AFTER SEEING THE DOGS
AND THE SMILES HAPPEN AND
THEN --
>> HEY.
YEAH.
YOU CAN'T HELP BUT SMILE WHEN
YOU SEE THESE GUYS AND THEY'RE
SO NICE, EVERYBODY'S PETTING
THEM.
I WANT TO REMIND THE VIEWERS
ABOUT WHAT IS GOING ON HERE.
THERE ARE PEOPLE LIKE SPENCER
AND THERE ARE PEOPLE LIKE PHILIP
AND WENDY COMING TO HELP OUT.
I WANT TO SAY THE KIDS AT
NEWTOWN SCHOOLS, THEY HAVE
GOTTEN BACK TO SCHOOL, BUT NOT
THE SANDY HOOK SCHOOLS.
NOT SURE WHEN THE SANDY HOOK
SCHOOLS WILL GO BACK, BUT
THEY'RE GOING TO SEE EXTRA
COUNSELORS, EXTRA POLICE
OFFICERS ON HAND AT SCHOOLS
TODAY AND UNTIL THEY GO BREAK
FOR THE CHRISTMAS HOLIDAYS.
AND ALSO THE TEACHERS UNION HERE
SAYS THEY'RE GOING TO HAVE
PEOPLE TO TALK TO THE STUDENTS,
BUT ONLY WHEN IT IS AGE
APPROPRIATE THAT THEY'LL TALK TO
THEM.
BUT, AGAIN, NOT EXACTLY SURE
WHEN THE SANDY HOOK STUDENTS
WILL GO BACK.
WASN'T
I WANT TO BRING IN WENDY
TERRELL, AN AUTHOR OF A
CHILDREN'S BOOK AND YOUR BOOK IS
CALLED "GUARDIAN OF DREAMS,"
RIGHT?
>> YES.
>> WHY IS THIS A GOOD RESOURCE
FOR KIDS.
SHOW THE BOOK.
>> IT IS A GOOD RESOURCE FOR
KIDS BECAUSE IT WAS WRITTEN
AFTER 9/11 WHEN CHILDREN WERE
HAVING A LOT OF NIGHTMARES.
AND GIVEN WHAT HAPPENED HERE
TODAY, THERE IS GOING TO BE A
LOT OF KIDS WHO ARE GOING TO BE
DEALING WITH THAT ISSUE IN
VOLUME AGAIN.
>> YOU SAID KIDS WHO HAVE DEALT
WITH A LOT OF TRAUMA IN THEIR
LIVES AND THAT WAS THE IMPETUS
BEHIND THIS.
THAT'S WHY YOU DID IT.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> YOU FIND IT HELPS.
>> YES, I HAVE.
I'VE GOTTEN A LOT OF FEEDBACK
FROM COUNSELORS AND PARENTS WHO
USED THE BOOK TO HELP THEIR
CHILDREN DEAL WITH THEIR ISSUES
AND DISAPPEAR THAT NIGHTMARE WAY
AND CREATE ANOTHER IMAGE IN ITS
PLACE.
>> YOU'RE A FORMER NEW YORK CITY
POLICE OFFICER?
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
>> HOW DID YOU PREPARE WHEN YOU
WERE A POLICE OFFICER FOR
TRAUMATIC EVENTS LIKE THIS?
BECAUSE, BROOKE BALDWIN HAS BEEN
TALKING TO THE RESCUERS AND THEY
ARE VERY EMOTIONAL.
THEY CAN'T BELIEVE WHAT THEY
SAW.
SO HOW DID YOU PREPARE WHEN YOU
WERE DOING THAT?
>> IT IS NOT REALLY SOMETHING
YOU CAN PREPARE FOR.
AND REALLY IT IS THE -- IT IS IN
THE MOMENT.
YOU REALLY DON'T HAVE THAT
OPPORTUNITY TO DEAL -- TO
EXPRESS YOUR EMOTIONS AT THAT --
IN THAT MOMENT IN TIME.
IT IS ONLY AFTERWARDS REALLY YOU
HAVE A CHANCE TO PROCESS IT.
>> I UNDERSTAND THAT YESTERDAY
YOU MET WITH GRIEF COUNSELORS AT
VARIOUS SCHOOLS.
>> AT THE GRIEVING CENTER, YES.
>> AT THE GRIEVING CENTER.
TELL US ABOUT THAT.
>> BASICALLY I DONATED SOME
BOOKS THERE SO THEY HAD THE
OPPORTUNITY TO USE THAT WITH THE
KIDS IN BEING ABLE TO, AS A TOOL
FOR THEM TO USE THE BOOK THAT
CAN HELP THEM COPE WITH WHAT'S
BEEN GOING ON.
>> IT IS IMPORTANT TO BE HERE
BECAUSE --
>> IT IS IMPORTANT TO BE HERE.
IT IS IMPORTANT, I THINK, TO
FIND OUT HOW YOU CAN CONTRIBUTE
IN A WAY THAT IS GOING TO BE
HELPFUL TO THE COMMUNITY HERE.
>> LET'S SEE THE BOOK.
OPEN IT UP A LITTLE BIT.
IS IT PICTURES OR STORIES OR
WHAT DO YOU HAVE?
>> IT IS A -- A PICTURE STORY.
AND IT IS A STORY ABOUT A RABBIT
WHO WAKES UP FROM A NIGHTMARE.
>> YEAH.
>> AND THE NIGHTMARE BEING A
FEMALE HORSE.
SO IT IS A PLAY.
HELPS YOU TO DISAPPEAR THE
NIGHTMARE AWAY.
>> ANY RESOURCE THAT CHILDREN
CAN GET AT THIS POINT IS
IMPORTANT.
THANK YOU, WENDY TERRELL.
>> THANK YOU.
>> WE APPRECIATE IT.
THANK YOU, SPENCER.
ALL THE FOLKS WHO ARE HERE.
BROOKE, YOU'VE BEEN HERE.
IT'S AMAZING.
I WAS SITTING HAVING LUNCH A
MOMENT AGO AND SOMEONE WALKED IN
JUST WITH A BOX OF THESE,
PRINTED THEM, SAYS WE ARE SANDY
HOOK, WE CHOOSE LOVE.
AND EVERY SINGLE PERSON IN THAT
RESTAURANT SAID I WANT ONE FOR
MY SCHOOL.
I WANT ONE FOR MY BUSINESS.
I WANT ONE TO PUT IN THE WINDOW
OF MY HOME.
AND THAT'S WHAT THEY'RE DOING
HERE.
THEY'RE CHOOSING LOVE INSTEAD OF
HAVING THE COMMUNITY BE
REMEMBERED FOR THIS HORRIBLE
EVENT, BROOKE.
>> YEAH.
IT IS QUITE SOMETHING TO WATCH
ON TV, BUT TO BE THERE IN
PERSON, AND SEE THE MEMORIALS,
TALK TO THE PEOPLE, IT'S
STUNNING.
IT'S GUT WRENCHING.
DON LEMON, WE'LL COME BACK TO
YOU MOMENTARILY.
PART OF THIS STORY, WE HAVE TO
TALK ABOUT GUN CONTROL.
THE DEBATE RAGES ONCE AGAIN.
IF YOU LOOK AT SOME OF THESE PRO
GUN RIGHTS FOLKS, NRA, FACEBOOK,
CRICKETS HAVE DEACTIVATED THEIR
FACEBOOK SITE, NO TWEETS.
NOT A LOT FROM THEM THE LAST
COUPLE OF DAYS.
AND WE LEARNED ACCORDING TO
FORBES, WE'LL HAVE THIS
CONVERSATION UP NEXT, THE
BUSHMASTER RIFLE, A
MILITARY-STYLE RIFLE THAT THE
SHOOTER USED ON FRIDAY, TEACHERS
MAY HAVE BEEN INDIRECTLY GIVING
TO THIS COMPANY THAT MAKES THIS
RIFLE.
THAT'S NEXT.
AND A CHOICE.
TAKE TYLENOL OR TAKE ALEVE,
THE #1 RECOMMENDED PAIN
RELIEVER BY ORTHOPEDIC DOCTORS.
JUST TWO ALEVE
CAN KEEP PAIN AWAY ALL DAY.
BACK TO THE NEWS.
I'M GOING TO DREAM
ABOUT THAT STEAK.
ABOUT THAT TIRAMISU.
WHAT A NIGHT, HUH?
BUT, UM, CAN THE TEST DRIVE
BE OVER NOW?
HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A PASSAT.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN, $0 DUE AT SIGNING,
$0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
>>> WE ARE TRACKING THE GROWING
DEBATE OVER POSSIBLE NEW GUN
CONTROL LAWS.
SOME LAWMAKERS CALLING FOR
RESTRICTIONS OR A NEW DISCUSSION
OF THIS PARTICULAR ISSUE.
BUT THE GUN RIGHTS SIDE OF THE
ARGUMENT, IT IS MOSTLY QUIET.
THE NATIONAL RIFLE ASSOCIATION
HAS BEEN SILENT SINCE BEFORE
FRIDAY'S SHOOTINGS.
WE HAVE GONE TO THE FACEBOOK
PAGE, IT HAS BEEN DEACTIVATED,
NO NEW TWEETS FROM THE NRA, NO
NEW POSTINGS ON ITS WEBSITE, BUT
THE GROUP'S CRITICS, THEY ARE
SPEAKING OUT.
>> SHAME ON THE NRA.
SHAME ON THE NRA.
>> THE NRA KNOWN FOR ITS
POWERFUL D.C. LOBBYING
OPERATION, YOU SEE EVERYONE OUT
AND ABOUT, THIS WAS YESTERDAY,
THIS IS RIGHT ON CAPITOL HILL.
DEMONSTRATORS MARCHED OUTSIDE
THE OFFICES THERE, CHANTING
SHAME ON THE NRA.
TEXAS GOVERNOR RICK PERRY,
HOWEVER, HE IS SPEAKING OUT AT A
TEA PARTY EVENT.
HE CAME DOWN IN FAVOR OF THE
RIGHT TO CARRY A LEGALLY
PURCHASED CONCEALED WEAPON, JUST
ABOUT ANYWHERE IN TEXAS,
INCLUDING IN SCHOOLS.
>> IF YOU GO THROUGH THE PROCESS
AND YOU HAVE BEEN DUALLY
BACKGROUNDED AND TRAINED AND YOU
ARE A CONCEALED HANDGUN LICENSED
CARRYING INDIVIDUAL, YOU SHOULD
BE ABLE TO CARRY YOUR HANDGUN
ANYWHERE IN THIS STATE.
>> STILL, NO OFFICIAL WORD AS
FAR AS WHAT ACTIONS THE
PRESIDENT MAY BE TAKING HERE.
BUT WE KNOW THE PRESIDENT MET
MONDAY WITH TOP AIDES, MULTIPLE
CABINET MEMBERS INCLUDING THE
EDUCATION SECRETARY AND THE
ATTORNEY GENERAL.
NOW, THERE IS A COMPANY, DON, I
WANT YOU TO TALK ABOUT HERE,
THAT APPARENTLY MAKES THIS
RIFLE, THIS BUSHMASTER RIFLE, IT
IS OWNED BY A PRIVATE INVESTMENT
GROUP.
WHAT IS THE STORY HERE?
>> WELL, BROOKE, THE PRIVATE
INVESTMENT GROUP IS CALLED
SERBRUS.
THEY SAID THEY'RE GOING TO SELL
THAT WEAPONS COMPANY.
BUT NOW THE CALIFORNIA TEACHERS
RETIREMENT SYSTEM IS A BIG
INVESTOR IN THAT FUND AND MAKING
THEM AN INDIRECT INVESTOR IN THE
MAKER OF BUSHMASTER RIFLES.
YOU CAN IMAGINE THERE IS A BIT
OF AN ISSUE HERE.
I WANT TO GO TO DON PRIMAC OF
FORTUNE.
HE BROKE THIS STORY.
DAN, HOW DID THIS -- THE
CALIFORNIA TEACHERS UNION BECOME
INVOLVED IN THIS SORT OF
INVESTMENT THING WITH A COMPANY
THAT MAKES BUSHMASTER RIFLE?
>> THE CALIFORNIA TEACHERS
PENSION, THE LARGEST PENSION FOR
PUBLIC SCHOOL TEACHERS IN
AMERICA, IT INVESTS A LOT IN
PRIVATE EQUITY FUNDS THAT DO
EVERYTHING FROM HEALTH CARE TO
RETAIL TO MANUFACTURING.
SERBRUS IS A DIVERSIFIED FUNDS.
THOSE FUNDS INVESTED IN FREEDOM
GROUP OR CREATED FREEDOM GROUP,
THEY BOUGHT BUSHMASTER AND
STARTED ADDING ON, ADDING ON TO
MAKE WHAT IS CURRENTLY THE
LARGEST U.S. GUN MANUFACTURER.
>> SO, DAN, IS THIS LIKE WHEN
YOU INVEST IN YOUR 401(k) OR
WHATEVER, WHATEVER INVESTMENT
YOU MIGHT HAVE, AND IT IS IN A
MUTUAL FUND AND YOU DON'T KNOW
WHICH COMPANIES ARE IN THAT
MUTUAL FUND.
IS THAT HOW IT IS OR DID THEY
HAVE DIRECT KNOWLEDGE THAT THIS
COMPANY WAS A MAKER OF THESE
RIFLES?
>> NO, IT IS DIFFERENT.
FIRST OF ALL, IT IS DIFFERENT
BECAUSE OF THE LONG-TERM
INVESTMENT.
UNLIKE YOUR 401(k), IF YOU
WANTED TO PULL YOUR MONEY OUT,
YOU CAN'T.
ONCE YOU'RE IN, YOU'RE IN,
UNLESS YOU DID A PRIVATE SALE
WITH SOMEONE ELSE.
BUT THEY KNOW WHAT'S IN IT.
THESE ARE LARGE TRANSACTIONS,
AND FOR CALLISTERS WHICH
COMMITTED $500 MILLION TO ONE OF
THESE FUNDS THEY DON'T GIVE A
$500 MILLION CHECK UP FRONT.
THEY SAY WE'LL GIVE YOU THIS
MONEY AND EVERY TIME THEY DO A
DEAL, IT ASKS FOR A PIECE OF THE
MONEY TO DO THE DEAL, IN THE
CASE OF FREEDOM GROUP, THEY
WOULD HAVE ASKED FOR MONEY TO DO
BUSHMASTER AND SO ON.
PLUS, FREEDOM GROUP FILED TO GO
PUBLIC IN 2009.
CALLISTERS WOULD HAVE KNOWN
ABOUT THAT AND GOTTEN QUARTERLY
UPDATES FROM THE FIRM.
>> SO, DAN, LET ME ASK YOU, WHY
IS CERBERUS SELLING THE COMPANY
THAT MAKES THE GUNS AND THE
AMMUNITION?
>> THEY HAVEN'T EXACTLY
EXPLAINED IT.
THEY PUT OUT A STATE THIS
MORNING SAYING THEY FEEL WHAT
HAPPENED IN NEWTOWN, IS A,
QUOTE, THEIR TERM, A WATER SHED
EVENT AND CAUSED THEM TO
RECONSIDER.
IT IS NOT AN INVESTMENT
DECISION.
IN ALL MY TIME COVERING PRIVATE
EQUITY, THIS IS THE FIRST TIME I
BELIEVE I'VE SEEN A PRIVATE
EQUITY FIRM DECIDE TO SELL A
COMPANY, A LARGE COMPANY, FOR
SOMETHING OTHER THAN INVESTMENT.
BECAUSE CLEARLY THIS IS NOT A
GOOD TIME TO SELL A GUN COMPANY.
THEY CLEARLY BELIEVE THAT
WHETHER IT IS FROM PRESSURE FROM
INVESTORS LIKE THE TEACHERS
PENSION, WHICH APPARENTLY CALLED
CERBERUS YESTERDAY AFTERNOON
AFTER OUR ORIGINAL REPORT OR
OTHER INVESTORS, THEY'RE GETTING
PRESSURE ON THIS FUND AND
THEY'RE PROBABLY CONCERNED THEY
WON'T BE ABLE TO RAISE MORE
MONEY IN THE FUTURE FROM THESE
PENSIONS AND THESE ENDOWMENTS IF
THEY DON'T DO SOMETHING HERE.
PLUS, ONE FINAL THING, THE
FOUNDER AND CEO, STEVE FEINBERG,
HIS FATHER HAPPENS TO LIVE IN
NEWTOWN.
>> DAN PRIMACK OF FORTUNE BROKE
THIS STORY.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
IF YOU GET NEW INFORMATION,
FOLLOW UP WITH US.
WE APPRECIATE IT.
BROOKE, A LOT OF PEOPLE WILL BE
CHECKING TO SEE IF -- I'M SURE
IF THEY HAVE INVESTMENTS IN
THESE COMPANIES AND AS YOU SAID,
NOT A GOOD TIME NOW TO HAVE --
TO BE A COMPANY THAT MAKES GUNS,
ESPECIALLY AUTOMATIC WEAPONS.
AND, YOU KNOW, AMMUNITIONS
COMPANIES AS WELL.
WE'LL BE FOLLOWING UP ON THIS
STORY, THESE STORIES A LOT, I'M
SURE.
>> DIFFERENT VAIN, I KNOW
SOMETHING A LOT OF THE CREWS IN
NEWTOWN ARE SEEING ARE HEARSES
DRIVE THROUGH TOWN AND THERE IS
THIS TOUGH GUT WRENCHING TASK OF
BURYING THESE CHILDREN, THE 6
AND 7-YEAR-OLDS.
COMING UP NEXT, I TALK TO THE
FIRST RESPONDERS IN NEWTOWN WHO
HELPING PROTECT THESE FAMILIES,
WHO WANT PRIVACY AT THE
CEMETERIES.
WE'RE RESPECTING THE PRIVACY,
BUT I SPOKE TO THESE TWO GUYS
LAST NIGHT ABOUT THE WHO
PROCESS, THIS VERY DIFFICULT
PROCESS OF BURYING THESE
CHILDREN.
[ sniffs ] I HAVE A COLD.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
We were going through so much
of the bargain detergent.
And the clothes
didn't look as good.
But since we switched to Tide
we use much less.
An amazing clean
for all three
of our full-grown
dependent bundles of joy.
That's my Tide,
what's yours?
>>> AS PARENTS THIS WEEK IN
NEWTOWN ARE LAYING THEIR 6 AND
7-YEAR-OLDS TO REST, MANY FIRST
RESPONDERS THERE, THEY'RE
VOLUNTEERING THEIR TIME THIS
WEEK AT THE CEMETERY, PROTECTING
THE FAMILIES, HELPING ENSURE
THEY GET THE PRIVACY THEY
DESERVE.
AND I SPOKE LAST NIGHT TO THESE
TWO WONDERFUL VOLUNTEER
FIREFIGHTERS IN NEWTOWN AT HOOK
AND LADDER, ONE OF WHOM IS THE
FATHER OF A FIRST GRADER, AND
THEY SHARED WITH ME JUST A
LITTLE BIT OF WHAT THEY HAVE
SEEN AND EXPERIENCED IN THE LAST
24 HOURS.
>> HOW DO YOU DESCRIBE THE
FUNERAL OF A 6 AND 7-YEAR-OLD?
>> IT'S ROUGH.
IT'S ROUGH.
LOOK HOW SAD A FUNERAL IS WHEN
IT IS AN ELDERLY PERSON.
THIS IS SOMEBODY THAT'S NOT YET
TO THAT POINT.
>> ARE YOU ANGRY OR MORE SAD?
>> THAT'S A GOOD QUESTION.
IF YOU ASK MY WIFE, I'M ANGRY.
I THINK I'M PRETTY SAD.
THIS IS DEVASTATING.
BUT ACCORDING TO HER, I'M PRETTY
ANGRY RIGHT NOW.
>> WHAT DO YOU GO HOME AT NIGHT
AND TELL HER?
>> I TELL HER I LOVE HER.
SHE ACTUALLY WORKS IN THE SCHOOL
SYSTEM, SO SHE KNEW EARLY ON
THAT THERE WAS SOMETHING GOING
ON TOO WHEN THEY WENT INTO
LOCKDOWN AND THE OTHER SCHOOL.
>> HE ALSO TOLD ME ABOUT HIS
FIRST GRADER WHO DOESN'T GO TO
SANDY HOOK, BUT WHO HE SAW ON
SATURDAY, AND WOULD NOT LET GO.
I KNOW A LOT OF YOU ARE
WONDERING HOW YOU CAN HELP THE
PEOPLE WHO ARE AFFECTED BY THIS
HORRENDOUS TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN.
YOU CAN.
WE HAVE PUT A LIST OF CHARITABLE
ORGANIZATIONS ON OUR WEBSITE.
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO IS GO TO
CNN.COM/IMPACT.
CNN.COM/IMPACT FOR WAYS YOU CAN
HELP.
DON, I KNOW IT IS AMAZING
WATCHING THE OUTPOURING, YOU
KNOW.
YOU'RE THERE AT THE MEMORIAL.
THERE ARE MULTIPLE MEMORIALS IN
AND AROUND NEWTOWN.
PEOPLE MAILING PACKAGES AND
LETTERS AND WREATHS, JUST
TRYING -- JUST SORT OF -- JUST
SHOWING THEY CARE.
>> YEAH, ABSOLUTELY, BROOKE.
AS YOU KNOW, YOU'VE SEEN IT, 26
OF EVERYTHING.
26 CANNEDLES.
26 TEDDY BEARS.
26 PIECES OF CANDY HERE.
26 PIECES OF LITTLE CANDELABRAS,
PEOPLE BUY NFLOWERS WITH 26
FLOWERS IN THEM.
JUST BEFORE WE WENT TO BREAK,
YOU WERE TALKING ABOUT THE
FUNERALS THAT ARE BEING HAD AND
SADLY THIS IS THE REALITY OF IT.
AS I DROVE IN HERE TODAY, TO
COME TO THIS STORY, I PASSED A
FUNERAL PROCESSION.
ALL THE CARS IN MY LANE PULLED
OVER AND WATCHED THE FUNERAL
PROCESSION GO BY IN THE OPPOSITE
WAY AND YOU SEE THE BLANK STARES
OF THE FACES OF THE PEOPLE
INSIDE THOSE CARS.
AND AS WE WERE STANDING HERE AS
WELL, ANOTHER FUNERAL PROCESSION
WENT BY AND MY PRODUCER AND I
LOOKED UP AND I HATE TO SAY
THIS, YOU CAN SEE, RIGHT
RAYLYNN, A WHITE CASKET, TINY
CASKET IN THE BACK.
REALITY IS SETTING IN FOR THESE
FOLKS WHO WERE JUST ABOUT TO
HAVE A CHRISTMAS AND NOW THEY'RE
HAVING TO DEAL WITH LAYING THEIR
LOVED ONES TO REST.
AND THE MAN RESPONSIBLE FOR
DOING ALL OF IT, 20 YEARS OLD,
20 YEARS OLD, WE'RE FINDING NEW
INFORMATION ABOUT HIM FROM THE
PEOPLE WHO KNEW HIM.
[ Female Announcer ]
RESEARCH SUGGESTS CELL HEALTH
PLAYS A KEY ROLE
THROUGHOUT OUR LIVES.
One A Day Women's 50+
IS A COMPLETE MULTIVITAMIN
DESIGNED FOR WOMEN'S HEALTH
CONCERNS AS WE AGE.
IT HAS 7 ANTIOXIDANTS
TO SUPPORT CELL HEALTH.
One A Day 50+.
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
♪
BECOMING
PART OF THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
TREES WILL TALK TO NETWORKS
WILL TALK TO SCIENTISTS
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE.
CARS WILL TALK TO ROAD SENSORS
WILL TALK TO STOPLIGHTS
ABOUT TRAFFIC EFFICIENCY.
THE AMBULANCE WILL TALK
TO PATIENT RECORDS
WILL TALK TO DOCTORS
ABOUT SAVING LIVES.
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
THE NEXT BIG THING?
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
♪
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
♪
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
>>> RICHARD ENGLE, THE CHIEF
FOREIGN CORRESPONDENT FOR NBC
NEWS AND HIS PRODUCTION CREW,
THEY ARE FREE TODAY AFTER BEING
HELD FOR FIVE DAYS INSIDE SYRIA.
ENGLE SPOKE WITH REPORTERS IN
TURKEY SHORTLY AFTER HE AND HIS
TEAM ESCAPED DURE, A DEADLY FIRE
FIGHT BETWEEN THEIR KIDNAPPERS
AND SYRIAN REBELS.
TAKE A LISTEN TO THIS.
>> THE LAST FIVE DAYS WERE VERY
DIFFICULT.
WE'RE VERY HAPPY TO BE OUT.
WE'RE VERY HAPPY TO BE BACK IN
TURKEY.
WE LOVE BEING HERE.
WE LOVE THIS COUNTRY.
AND WE APPRECIATE ALL THE HELP.
THE LAST FIVE DAYS ARE SOME DAYS
THAT WE WOULD RATHER FORGET.
>> THEY WOULD LIKE TO FORGET
THEM.
WE CAN TELL YOU THAT ENGLE AND
HIS TEAM VANISHED THURSDAY AFTER
CROSSING INTO NORTHWEST SYRIA
FROM TURKEY.
AND THOUGH NO ONE CLAIMED
RESPONSIBILITY FOR THIS
KIDNAPPING, ENGLE SAID HE THINKS
HIS CAPTORS WERE PART OF THIS
MILITIA LOYAL TO SYRIAN
PRESIDENT BASHAR AL ASSAD, AND
TRAINED BY IRAN'S REVOLUTIONARY
GUARD.
HE ALSO SAID THEY PLANNED TO
TRADE THE JOURNALISTS FOR
HOSTAGES HELD BY SYRIAN REBELS.
ENGLE SPOKE AGAIN TODAY ABOUT
THE ORDEAL.
>> THEY TOOK US TO A SERIES OF
SAFE HOUSES AND INTERROGATION
PLACES, AND THEY KEPT US
BLINDFOLDED, BOUND.
WE WEREN'T PHYSICALLY BEATEN OR
TORTURED.
IT WAS A LOT OF PSYCHOLOGICAL
TORTURE, THREATS OF BEING
KILLED, THEY MADE US CHOOSE
WHICH ONE OF US WOULD BE SHOT
FIRST.
AND WHEN WE REFUSED, THERE WERE
MOCK SHOOTINGS.
THEY PRETENDED TO SHOOT GAZY
SEVERAL TIMES AND WHEN YOU'RE
BLINDFOLDED, AND TOLD -- AND
THEN THEY FIRED THE GUN UP IN
THE AIR.
IT CAN BE VERY TRAUMATIC
EXPERIENCE.
AND AT THE END OF THIS, WE WERE
BEING MOVED TO YET ANOTHER
LOCATION IN THE -- AROUND 11:00
LAST NIGHT, LOCAL TIME.
AND AS WE WERE MOVING ALONG THE
ROAD, THE KIDNAPPERS CAME ACROSS
A REBEL CHECKPOINT.
SOMETHING THEY HADN'T EXPECTED.
AND SO WE WERE IN THE BACK OF,
LIKE, WHEN YOU THINK OF AS A
MINIVAN, AND AS WE WERE DRIVING
ALONG THE ROAD, THE KIDNAPPERS
SAW THIS CHECKPOINT, STARTED A
GUNFIGHT WITH IT, TWO OF THE
KIDNAPPERS WERE KILLED.
WE CLIMBED OUT OF THE VEHICLE
AND THE REBELS TOOK US, WE SPENT
THE NIGHT WITH THEM, WE DIDN'T
GET MUCH SLEEP.
>> AGAIN, RICHARD ENGLE SPEAKING
OUT TODAY.
CNN WANTS YOU TO KNOW, WE GOT
WORD LAST THURSDAY NIGHT THAT
RICHARD ENGLE AND HIS TEAM WERE
MISSING.
NBC NEWS ASKED US NOT TO REPORT
THE NEWS AND, OF COURSE, WE
COMPLIED WITH THAT REQUEST.
CNN HAS COMPLIED WITH SUCH
REQUESTS BEFORE AND LIKELY WILL
AGAIN.
OFTENTIMES IN FIRST COUPLE OF
DAYS AFTER A NONCOMBATANT GOES
MISSING, BE IT A JOURNALIST, A
MEMBER OF A NONGOVERNMENT
ORGANIZATION OR A COMPANY
EMPLOYEE, CNN IS ASKED, AS ARE
OTHER NEWS ORGANIZATIONS, TO
DELAY REPORTING THE STORY.
THE REASON IS SO THAT FACT
FINDING AND NEGOTIATIONS TO FREE
THEM CAN TAKE PLACE BEFORE THEIR
CAPTURE BECOMES A WORLDWIDE NEWS
EVENT.
HOSTAGE NEGOTIATORS SAY THAT
ONCE THE GLOBAL SPOTLIGHT IS ON
THE MISSING, THE HOSTAGES
VALUE -- THE VALUE OF THESE MEN
AND WOMEN MAKING IT MUCH, MUCH
MORE DIFFICULT TO NEGOTIATE
THEIR FREEDOM.
>>> HAWAII AND THE REST OF THE
NATION REMEMBER A GENTLE GIANT
OF THE U.S. SENATE.
>> WITH A HEAVY HEART, IT BID
ALOHA, ALOHA TO MY GOOD FRIEND,
COLLEAGUE AND BROTHER, DANIEL
INOU
INOUYE.
>> YOU WILL BE EXCUSED IF YOU
DIDN'T KNOW THAT BEFORE HIS
DEATH YESTERDAY.
HAWAII'S DANIEL INOUYE RANKED
THIRD IN THE LINE OF
PRESIDENTIAL SUCCESSION.
HE WAS THE SENATE PRO TEM, THE
SENIOR MEMBER OF THE SENATE'S
MAJORITY PARTY, HAVING SERVED 50
YEARS DURING HIS HALF CENTURY IN
OFFICE.
INOUYE MADE MANY, MANY FRIENDS,
LOTS HAPPEN.
BUT MADE REMARKABLY LITTLE
NOISE.
INITIALLY BARRED FROM SERVING IN
WORLD WAR II BECAUSE OF HIS
JAPANESE ROOTS, HE PETITIONED TO
GET HIMSELF INTO THE ARMY, WOUND
UP LOSING AN ARM, FOUGHT WITH
SUCH DISTINCTION THAT HE EARNED
THE MEDAL OF HONOR.
HE WAS FIRST ELECTED TO CONGRESS
BACK IN 1959, THE YEAR HAWAII
BECAME A STATE.
AND EARNED SUCH RESPECT HE WAS
NAMED TO COMMITTEE THAT
INVESTIGATED WATERGATE,
INVESTIGATED THE IRAN/CONTRA,
ALSO ROSE TO THE TOP OF THE
POWERFUL SENATE APPROPRIATIONS
COMMITTEE, WHICH HELPED HIM
STEER FEDERAL DOLLARS TO HIS
BELOVED HAWAII.
HE DIED OF RESPIRATORY FAILURE.
HIS OFFICE SAYS HIS FINAL WORD
WAS, ALOHA.
>>> AND BACK TO NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
DON LEMON STANDING BY.
HEY, DON.
>> HEY, BROOKE.
WANT TO SHOW YOU SOME THINGS
THAT ARE GOING ON HERE.
SOME LADIES SHOWED UP AND
THEY'RE PUTTING CANDLES IN THE
DIRT, STICKING THEM DOWN IN THE
GROUND.
PEOPLE ARE WRITING CARDS AS WELL
AS THEY DROP OFF TEDDY BEARS.
HERE IS ONE TO CATHERINE
HUBBARD, ONE OF THE VICTIMS, ONE
FOR EMILIE PARKER.
I CAN SEE INSIDE, WITHOUT EVEN
OPENING IT, I CAN SEE THERE SAY
SNOWMAN ON IT, A CHRISTMAS CARD
FOR THEM.
ONE FOR BENJAMIN WHEELER AS
WELL.
ONE OF THE VICTIMS AS WELL.
AND THERE IS ALSO -- MORE THINGS
IN THERE, NOT EXACTLY SURE WHAT
IT IS AND I'M NOT THE ONE TO
OPEN IT UP.
I'M SURE ALL OF THIS, IF THE
RAIN DOESN'T TAKE IT WAY, WILL
BE GIVEN TO THE FAMILY MEMBERS
OF THE VICTIMS IN TIME, IN TIME.
BECAUSE IT IS GOING TO TAKE A
WHILE BEFORE THEY CAN EVEN BE
ABLE TO ACCEPT AND RECEIVE ALL
OF THIS.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE MORE FROM
NEWTOWN AND WITH MY COLLEAGUE AS
WELL, BROOKE BALDWIN, BACK IN
ATLANTA, RIGHT AFTER THIS BREAK.
ALLY BANK.
WHY THEY HAVE A
RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
TONIGHT OUR GUEST,
THOMAS SARGENT.
NOBEL LAUREATE
IN ECONOMICS,
AND ONE OF THE MOST CITED
ECONOMISTS IN THE WORLD.
PROFESSOR SARGENT,
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT CD RATES WILL
BE IN TWO YEARS?
NO.
IF HE CAN'T, NO ONE CAN.
THAT'S WHY ALLY HAS
A RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
ALLY BANK.
YOUR MONEY NEEDS AN ALLY.
>>> WE'RE TALKING ABOUT GETTING
THE MOST FROM YOUR MONEY.
WE ALL WANT TO DO THAT.
WITH ME THIS HOUR, LYNETTE C
CALFAWNY COX AND DAVID NOVAK.
>> WHAT DO I HAVE TO DO TO GET
10% ON MY MONEY?
>> WOULDN'T WE ALL LIKE TO KNOW?
WOULDN'T WE ALL LIKE TO KNOW?
>> TALL ORDER.
I'LL BE NICE.
YOU HAVE TO HAVE REALISTIC
EXPECTATIONS, SO FAR.
I SAW HE WAS AN ELDERLY
GENTLEMAN.
IF YOU'RE USED TO GETTING A
COUPLE OF PERCENTAGE POINTS, YOU
HAVE TO TAKE ON MORE RISK.
THERE IS NO WAY TO DO THAT.
AND IT IS NOT GUARANTEED.
LOOK AT THINGS LIKE STOCKS,
GROWTH STOCKS, MUTUAL FUNDS ARE
AN OPTION, OF COURSE.
BUT RECOGNIZE THERE REALLY IS A
TRADE-OFF BETWEEN RISK AND
REWARD.
THE HIGHER THE RETURNS THAT YOU
WANT TO GENERATE, 10% IS PRETTY
HIGH IN THIS MARKET, THE MORE
RISK YOU HAVE TO BE WILLING TO
TAKE ON.
>> MAYBE HE'LL GET 10% ON 25% OF
HIS INVESTMENTS AND BE
CONSERVATIVE WITH THE REST.
>> RIGHT.
>> THAT'S AN OPTION.
THE OTHER THING YOU NEED TO BE
CAREFUL ABOUT IS IF HE REALLY
WANTS TO BE AGGRESSIVE AND
INVEST IN STOCKS, HE NEEDS TO
UNDERSTAND THAT IT IS SOMETHING
THAT HAS TO BE FOR THE
LONG-TERM.
AND THAT HE NEEDS TO HOLD IT AND
UNDERSTAND THAT MAYBE GOING UP
AND DOWN A BIT IN A GIVEN YEAR,
IF HE'S COMFORTABLE WITH THAT,
IT IS POSSIBLE TO GET CLOSER TO
WHAT HE WANTS.
IF HE'S NOT, IT IS PROBABLY NOT
LIKELY.
>> APPRECIATE IT.
IF YOU HAVE A QUESTION YOU WANT
OUR EXPERTS TO TACKLE, UPLOAD A
30-SECOND VIDEO WITH YOUR
QUESTION TO IREPORT.COM.
>>> WE HAVE BEEN TELLING YOU THE
STORIES OF THE PEOPLE WHO LOST
THEIR LIVES HERE, BUT THE MAN
THE POLICE BELIEVE IS
RESPONSIBLE FOR THIS, THE
SHOOTER, WE'RE LEARNING NEW
INFORMATION ABOUT HIM.
AND CNN'S SUSAN CANDIOTTI SPOKE
WITH ONE OF HIS FORMER
CLASSMATES.
>> Reporter: AMONG THE STEADY
STREAM OF PEOPLE DRAWN TO THIS
MEMORIAL HONORING VICTIMS, A
FORMER SCHOOLMATE OF THE ALLEGED
KILLER.
WHEN YOU THINK OF THIS, DOES
YOUR MIND GO TO YOUR FRIEND?
>> OBVIOUSLY IT DOES BECAUSE,
YOU KNOW, HE'S A VERY BIG PART
IN THIS EVENT.
I'M NOT REALLY SURE WHAT TO
THINK OF IT.
>> Reporter: SADLY HE'S THE
REASON FOR IT.
>> YEAH.
>> Reporter: ALAN DIAZ MAY HAVE
BEEN AS CLOSE AS ANYONE COULD
COME TO BEING A FRIEND OF ADAM
LANZA WHEN HE WAS A SOPHOMORE AT
NEWTOWN HIGH SCHOOL AND DIAZ WAS
A FRESHMAN IN 2008.
>> A VERY INTELLIGENT PERSON, HE
REALLY WAS.
THE WAY HE ACTED AROUND OTHER
PEOPLE WAS JUST VERY WITHDRAWN
AND REALLY QUIET.
>> Reporter: A LITTLE DIFFERENT?
>> YEAH.
>> Reporter: THEY WERE IN THE
HIGH SCHOOL TECH CLUB TOGETHER,
SPENT A LOT OF TIME ON
COMPUTERS.
ADAM HAD HIS OWN STYLE OF
DRESSING.
>> HE HAD THE STEREOTYPICAL NERD
LOOK, LIKE, KHAKI PANTS, BELT,
TUCKED IN SHIRT, EVEN HAD A
LITTLE COMPUTER CASE, LIKE A
BRIEF CASE INSTEAD OF A BACKPACK
LIKE EVERYONE ELSE.
HE EVEN HAD A LITTLE POCKET
PROTECTOR HE HAD PENS IN.
>> Reporter: HE DOESN'T KNOW
WHETHER LANZA WAS BULLIED.
HE KEPT TO HIMSELF.
>> WE ALL KIND OF KNEW THAT,
LIKE, YOU KNOW, HE HAD PROBLEMS
SOCIALLY.
AND WE KIND OF HAD A FEELING
THAT THERE MIGHT HAVE BEEN
SOMETHING WRONG WITH HIM, BUT WE
NEVER ASKED, NEVER THOUGHT IT
WAS OUR PLACE TO DO SO.
>> Reporter: BACK THEN HIS
SCHOOLMATE'S MOM ONCE INVITED
ALL HIS FRIENDS TO THE HOUSE TO
PLAY VIDEO GAMES.
ONE WAS STAR CRAFT, KIND OF A
WAR GAMES IN SPACE.
ANOTHER WAS WAR CRAFT 3, WHERE
AS THE AD SAYS, SURVIVAL IS A
MATTER OF STRATEGY.
>> THE BURNING SHADOW COMES TO
CONSUME US ALL.
>> WAR CRAFT 3 WAS REALLY FUN.
SO, YOU KNOW, HE WAS REALLY INTO
GAMES AND IF I RECALL HE
ACTUALLY PICKED UP ON STAR CRAFT
REALLY QUICKLY.
>> Reporter: WHEN LANZA LEFT
HIGH SCHOOL AND WAS HOME
SCHOOLED, DIAZ LOST TOUCH.
BUT HE RAN INTO LANZA'S MOTHER
NANCY ABOUT TWO YEARS AGO.
>> I REMEMBER HER, LIKE,
MENTIONING THAT HE STARTED GOING
TO THE SHOOTING RANGE WITH HER
AND MY INITIAL RESPONSE TO THAT
WAS, I NEVER REALLY IMAGINED
ADAM ONE TO EVER EVEN HOLD A
GUN.
>> Reporter: WHY DO YOU SAY
THAT?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE BECAUSE IN MY MIND I DON'T
IMAGINE SHY, QUIET PEOPLE, YOU
KNOW, GOING TO A SHOOTING RANGE.
I NEVER REALLY CAN MAKE THAT
ASSOCIATION.
>> Reporter: INVESTIGATORS ARE
TRACKING HOW OFTEN LANZA HAD
BEEN TO GUN RANGES.
THEY DON'T YET KNOW HOW MANY SO
FAR.
THEY HAVE PROVEN HE'S BEEN TO
TARGET PRACTICE ABOUT SIX MONTHS
AGO.
AND FOR SEVERAL YEARS MOTHER AND
SON WENT AT LEAST ONCE TOGETHER.
ALAN'S OLDER SISTER WENT TO
SCHOOL WITH THE SHOOTER'S OLDER
BROTHER.
AND SHE WAS FRIENDS WITH HER
MOTHER WHO WENT TO HER BRIDAL
SHOWER LAST YEAR.
>> WHY HER?
SHE WAS JUST -- IT WAS A SHOCK.
SHE WAS ALWAYS A HAPPY PERSON.
>> Reporter: DO YOU NOW THINK OF
HIM AS AN EVIL PERSON?
BECAUSE OF WHAT HE DID?
>> AT ONE POINT HE WAS A GOOD
KID.
THE EVENTS THAT HE DID THAT DAY
MAY HAVE BEEN EVIL, BUT BEFORE
THEN, HE WAS JUST ANOTHER KID.
>> Reporter: UNTIL SOMETHING
MADE HIM SNAP.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI, CNN, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> ALL RIGHT, SUSAN.
AND, BROOKE, YOU KNOW, PEOPLE,
THE MORE THEY HEAR ABOUT THE
SHOOTER, THE MORE DETAILS, EVEN
US, WE STILL DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHY.
BEFORE I GO BACK TO YOU IN
ATLANTA, I WANT TO SAY YOU SAW
THIS, BROOKE, PEOPLE JUST
WALKING UP TO US AND YOU WALKED
UP TO US.
TELL ME YOUR NAME.
>> JAMIE.
>> YOU'RE OVERCOME.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN OUT HERE?
>> I'VE BEEN OUT HERE ALL DAY.
JUST TRYING TO LEAVE A LITTLE
SOMETHING AT EACH MEMORIAL FOR
THE KIDS.
AND FOR THE VICTIMS.
>> YEAH.
WHAT DID YOU WANT TO SAY TO US?
>> I JUST -- I JUST CAN'T
BELIEVE THAT THIS KIND OF A
TRAGEDY COULD HAPPEN.
AND JUST WALKING THROUGH THE
TOWN, I MEAN, EVERYTHING IS SO
BEAUTIFUL.
AND THERE IS SO MUCH LOVE HERE.
BUT IT'S SO HARD.
AND I HAVE FRIENDS THAT LIVE
HERE.
AND THANK GOD THEIR KIDS ARE
OKAY.
BUT THIS IS JUST MIND BLOWING.
AND THE MOST THAT I CAN DO IS
JUST COME DOWN AND SHOW SUPPORT
FOR ANYBODY WHO NEEDS ANYTHING.
>> WELL, THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
WE APPRECIATE THE LOVE YOU'RE
SHOWING FOR EVERYONE.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
THANK YOU.
GOD BLESS YOU GUYS.
YOU'RE DOING A WONDERFUL JOB.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
It's hard to see opportunity
in today's challenging
environment.
Unless you have the right
perspective.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
has the vision
and experience to look beyond
the obvious.
We'll uncover opportunities,
find hidden risk,
and make success a reality.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
>>> TOP OF THE HOUR HERE, LIVE
ON CNN.
GOOD TO BE WITH YOU.
I'M BROOKE BALDWIN LIVE AT THE
CNN WORLD HEADQUARTERS IN
ATLANTA.
MY COLLEAGUE THERE, DON LEMON,
IN THE MIDST OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WHERE, TODAY, TWO
MORE YOUNG VICTIMS ARE BEING
LAID TO REST.
SERVICES FOR 6-YEAR-OLD JESSICA
REKOS WERE HELD AT ST. ROSE OF
LIMA CATHOLIC CHURCH AS HER
RELATIVES GRIEVE, THEY'RE ALSO
TRYING TO HELP HER BABY BROTHER
TRAVIS UNDERSTAND WHY HE CAN'T
PLAY WITH HIS BEST FRIEND
ANYMORE.
HER FAMILY SAYS SHE LOVED
EVERYTHING HORSES.
HORSE MOVIES, DRAWING HORSES,
APPARENTLY ASKED SANTA CLAUS FOR
A NEW PAIR OF COW GIRL BOOTS
THIS UPCOMING CHRISTMAS.
>>> ALSO TODAY, 6-YEAR-OLD JAMES
MATTIOLI WAS BURIED.
THAT FUNERAL ALSO HELD AT ST.
ROSE OF LIMA CHURCH THERE IN
NEWTOWN.
THE FAMILY POSTED A PUBLIC
OBITUARY ON THE FUNERAL HOME'S
WEBSITE CALLING HIM, QUOTE, OUR
BELOVED PRINCE.
THEY SAY JAMES LOVED SCHOOL,
SPENT HOURS AND HOURS PLAYING
HOCKEY.
AND THESE ARE JUST TWO OF THE 20
LITTLE LIVES LOST FRIDAY
MORNING.
DON LEMON, I KNOW YOU AND MANY
OF THE CREW WATCHING SOME OF THE
E-MAIL TRAFFIC TALKING ABOUT HOW
DIFFICULT IT IS BEING IN TOWN,
WATCHING THE HEARSES PASSING BY
AND SEEING THE TEENY TINY
CASKETS INSIDE.
>> YEAH.
IT IS REALLY -- IT IS REALLY
SAD, BROOKE.
I HAVE FRIENDS HERE, THEY DON'T
REALIZE I'M ON TELEVISION,
THEY'RE COMING UP AND TALKING TO
ME.
AND THEY CAN.
YOU GUYS CAN INTERRUPT ME
ANYTIME.
YOU'RE PATTY.
>> RIGHT.
>> AND YOU'RE JESSY.
WHERE ARE YOU FROM?
>> FAIRFIELD?
>> FAIRFIELD.
YOU'RE OUT HERE BECAUSE --
>> I ATTEND A CHURCH FROM WHERE
A LOT OF PEOPLE FROM NEWTOWN GO
AND ONE OF MY BEST FRIEND'S
GRANDDAUGHTERS IS IN THE FIRST
GRADE AT SANDY HOOK.
>> AND THEY'RE GETTING OFF MY
MICROPHONE BUT THEY WALKED UP TO
ME AND TALKED TO ME AND ANYBODY
CAN, DOESN'T MATTER IF WE'RE ON
TELEVISION.
THANK YOU FOR COMING OUT.
BLESS YOU.
WE HAVE BEEN HERE, OF COURSE,
FOR A COUPLE OF DAYS, BROOKE.
AND WE SAW THIS MEMORIAL, JUST
GROW TREMENDOUSLY HERE.
IT JUST STARTED JUST OVER THERE
WAY COUPLE OF CANDLES AND NOW IT
HAS GROWN SO FAR, POLICE HAVE TO
DIRECT TRAFFIC HERE.
AND THERE ARE LAYERS UPON LAYERS
OF TEDDY BEARS AND FLOWERS AND
CANDLES AND CARDS.
AND MOST PEOPLE ARE BRINGING 26
OF EVERY SINGLE THING.
AND IT DOESN'T MATTER THE COST.
DOESN'T MATTER.
THEY'RE BRINGING EXPENSIVE TEDDY
BEARS, EXPENSIVE FLOWER
ARRANGEMENTS, EXPENSIVE CANDLES,
THESE CANDLES THAT ARE SOLAR
THAT ARE HERE.
AND THEY JUST WANT TO COME OUT
AND SHOW THEIR SUPPORT.
I WANT TO TELL YOU ABOUT THE
SCHOOL SYSTEM HERE.
THEY ARE NOT GOING TO BE IN
SCHOOL AT LEAST THE FOLKS WHO
ARE IN SANDY HOOK, THEY'RE NOT
GOING TO BE IN SCHOOL, NEWTOWN
SCHOOLS WENT BACK TODAY.
THE KIDS WHO DID GO BACK IN THE
OTHER SCHOOL DISTRICTS, THEY'RE
GOING TO BE SEEING MORE
COUNSELORS, MORE POLICE OFFICERS
ON HAND, AND ALSO THE TEACHERS
UNION HERE SAYING THEY'RE GOING
TO TALK TO THE KIDS WITH
COUNSELORS, OF COURSE, AND IT IS
GOING TO BE AGE APPROPRIATE.
BUT I WANT TO BRING IN OUR KATE
BOLDUAN, SHE'S BEEN CHECKING UP
ON THE SCHOOLS.
YOU FOUND NEW INFORMATION.
THEY'RE NOT GOING BACK UNTIL
JANUARY.
WHAT OTHER THINGS ARE YOU
FINDING OUT?
>> WE HAVE OBTAINED THIS LETTER
FROM NEWTOWN SCHOOL OFFICIALS TO
FAMILY AND STAFF INFORMING THEM,
THERE WAS A LOT OF QUESTIONS OF
WHEN THE CHILDREN IN SANDY HOOK
WOULD BE BROUGHT BACK TO CLASS
AND IT IS INFORMING THEM,
FINALLY, A DEFINITIVE THING,
THEY WILL NOT BE GOING BACK
UNTIL JANUARY AFTER THE HOLIDAY,
WHICH THE HOLIDAY WAS SET TO
BEGIN ON FRIDAY.
BUT MEANTIME, THIS MAY BE ONE OF
THE MOVIE VANS WE'RE SEEING
BEHIND US RIGHT HERE THAT WAS
TAKING ALL THE MATERIALS FROM
SANDY HOOK TO MOVE TO THE NEW
FACILITY.
>> YOU'RE PROBABLY RIGHT.
>> THEY'RE MOVING ENTIRE
CLASSROOMS IN THESE VANS OVER TO
THIS NEW FACILITY BECAUSE THEY
WANT TO REPLICATE IT AS CLOSE AS
POSSIBLE TO EXACTLY WHAT THIS --
TO MAKE IT COMFORTABLE FOR THE
SANDY HOOK STUDENTS AND WHERE
THE TRUCKS ARE GOING, SIX MILES
AWAY, TO MONROE.
AND THEY'RE WORKING AROUND THE
CLOCK TO GET READY.
TRUCK LOADS FILLED WITH
EVERYTHING FROM DESKS TO
BULLETIN BOARDS LEAVING SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY, HEADING HERE TO
THE NEIGHBORING TOWN OF MONROE.
BOOK CASES, DESKS.
>> THAT'S THE STUDENTS'
MATERIALS, THE BACKPACKS THEY
LEFT.
WHEN THE CHILDREN COME IN,
WHENEVER THE SCHOOL IS STARTED,
THEY WILL WALK INTO A CLASSROOM
THAT LOOKED AS CLOSE AS POSSIBLE
AS THEIR CLASSROOM THAT THEY
LEFT.
>> Reporter: STEVE VAVRIK IS THE
TOWN'S CHIEF EXECUTIVE.
WHEN HE HEARD ABOUT THE HORROR
AT SANDY HOOK, HE OFFERED UP
CHALK HILL MIDDLE SCHOOL.
IT IS EMPTY BECAUSE IT CLOSED
RECENTLY.
HE MET WITH SOME OF THE STUDENTS
AND TEACHERS AT SUNDAY'S VIGIL.
>> MOST OF THEM WERE THANKFUL
THEY HAD A PLACE TO GO BACK TO
WORK.
THE CHILDREN AND THE TEACHERS
WERE -- IT WAS EMOTIONAL.
>> Reporter: ALL DAY CONTRACTORS
FROM AROUND THE REGION DONATED
THEIR TIME TO TRANSFORM THIS
FORMER MIDDLE SCHOOL INTO AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> JUST TO GIVE YOU A SENSE, I
MEAN, THE TOILETS ALL HAVE TO BE
REPLACED TO A SMALLER SIZE.
YOU KNOW, THINGS HAVE TO BE MADE
ACCESSIBLE, TOWEL DISPENSERS,
THINGS LIKE THAT, LOWERED.
>> Reporter: THIS IS MONROE'S
SCHOOL SUPERINTENDENT.
WHY IS IT IMPORTANT TO GET THE
STUDENTS OF SANDY HOOK INTO A
BUILDING LIKE CHALK HILL AND
BACK IN THEIR CLASSROOM?
>> WELL, THAT'S EXACTLY THE
SENSE OF NORMALCY THAT THEY NEED
TO BEGIN THE HEALING PROCESS.
AND TO FEEL SAFE AND PROTECTED
AND TO GET BACK INTO A ROUTINE.
>> Reporter: ONE CHANGE EVERY
PARENT WILL NOTICE AT SCHOOLS
ACROSS THE AREA AFTER SANDY
HOOK, POLICE PATROLS.
IS THAT A PROTECTIVE MEASURE?
IS THAT THE NEW NORMAL?
OR IS THAT MORE A WAY TO HELP
FAMILIES AND STUDENTS ALLEVIATE
SOME ANXIETY AS THEY RETURN TO
CLASS?
>> ALL OF THE ABOVE.
ALL OF THE ABOVE.
UNFORTUNATELY IT MAY BE THE NEW
NORMAL.
IT MAY BE THE WAY WE HAVE TO
TAKE ACTION IN THE FUTURE.
>> SO, KATE, WHEN IS THE SCHOOL
GOING TO BE READY?
DO WE KNOW?
>> THAT'S BEEN A QUESTION AS
WELL.
WE SPOKE WITH THE FIRE MARSHAL
FOR AN UPDATE.
ORIGINALLY YESTERDAY THEY
BELIEVED THE BUILDING COULD BE
READY AS EARLY AS TODAY.
AND THEN UP TO NEWTOWN SCHOOL
OFFICIALS WHEN THEY'RE READY TO
START CLASSES.
BUT THE UPDATE IS THEY'RE STILL
WORKING ON GETTING THE BUILDING
RECERTIFIED, GETTING THINGS LIKE
FIRE ALARMS, DOOR LOCKS,
SPRINKLER SYSTEMS UPDATED TO BE
READY FOR THE KIDS.
AND THE BUILDING WILL BE READY
MORE LIKELY TOWARD LATER IN THE
WEEK BUT WE KNOW WHEN THEIR
START DATE IS, THE BUILDING WILL
BE READY FOR SANDY HOOK AT THE
BEGINNING OF THE YEAR.
>> LET'S STEP OUT HERE AND TALK
AND LET THE PHOTOGRAPHER GO
OVER.
YOU CAN SEE -- LOOK AT THE
EXPENSIVE ARRANGEMENTS AND SOME
MONKS HERE ON THE SCENE.
WE'LL SEE MORE PEOPLE SHOW UP
BECAUSE THEY'RE COMING FROM
WORK.
IN A MOMENT OF TRANSPARENCY, IT
HAS BEEN NOTHING NEARLY AS TOUGH
AS WHAT THE FAMILIES ARE DEALING
WITH HERE.
BUT OUR COLLEAGUE, WOLF BLITZER,
SUCH AN AMAZING MAN, HE KNEW
THIS WAS VERY STRESSFUL FOR ALL
OF US.
TOOK US TO DIFFERENT LAST NIGHT.
WE WERE AT DINNER AND WE WERE
TALKING JUST ABOUT HOW TOUGH IT
IS SEEING THESE FAMILIES AND
EVEN THE RESCUE WORKERS.
AS YOU'VE BEEN AROUND TOWN TODAY
AND THE FUNERALS STARTED
YESTERDAY, AND TWO TODAY, WHAT
HAS BEEN YOUR BIGGEST
IMPRESSION?
>> MY BIGGEST IMPRESSION THE
ENTIRE TIME WE HAVE BEEN HERE,
YOU SEE IT HERE AND YOU SAW THE
MEMORIAL STARTED AS SMALL
MEMORIAL TO THE VICTIMS, AND
LOOK WHAT IT HAS GROWN INTO.
AN ENTIRE BLOCK AT THIS POINT.
IT CONTINUES TO GROW.
MY BIG IMPRESSION AS WE HAVE
BEEN HERE AND I'M HONORED TO BE
HERE WITH THIS COMMUNITY IS HOW
CLOSE THE COMMUNITY IS.
I'VE HEARD MORE AND MORE OFTEN
THAN NOT THAT SANDY HOOK, THE
TOWN, DOES NOT WANT TO BE
REMEMBERED AS THE TRAGEDY.
THEY WANT TO BE REMEMBERED AS
THE COMMUNITY THAT CAME TOGETHER
AND THEIR STRENGTH AND THEY
FOUGHT BACK AGAINST THE EVIL AND
THE TRAGEDY AND THEY WERE
TOGETHER AND THEY BECAME
STRONGER AND HEALED ALL TOGETHER
FOR IT.
>> I HAVE TO TELL YOU, YOU KNOW,
IT HAS BEEN REAL.
WE HAVE BEEN SAYING -- I'VE BEEN
ON THE VERGE OF TEARS AND CRIED
PRIVATELY.
BUT TODAY, AS I WAS COMING IN, I
TOLD OUR VIEWERS EARLIER, I
PASSED A FUNERAL PROCESSION.
AND HAD TO PULL OVER AND STOP.
I WAS ON THE PHONE WITH ONE OF
THE PRODUCERS AND I JUST STOPPED
AND PUT PHONE DOWN AND SEE THE
FACES OF THE PEOPLE INSIDE OF
THE CARS IN THE FUNERAL
PROCESSION.
STANDING HERE EARLIER IN THE
BACK, I KNOW IS TERRIBLE TO SAY,
BUT JUST A LITTLE WHITE CASKET
AND YOU REALIZE HOW -- IT IS
UNFATHOMABLE.
>> AND YOU REALIZE THAT AT
VARIOUS DIFFERENT STEPS, IT HIT
ME WHEN I SAW A MOTHER AND HER
CHILD IN A CAFE AND SAW THIS
SMALL CHILD, THE SAME AGE AS THE
KIDS THAT WERE IN THE CLASSROOM,
AND WHEN YOU SEE THOSE SMALL,
SMALL CASKETS, IT IS, YOU KNOW,
IT IS ONE REMINDER AFTER ANOTHER
OF JUST HOW HORRIFIC AND WE
HEARD IT ON AIR, WE HEARD IT
FROM EVERYONE WE TALKED TO,
THERE ARE NO WORDS AND THAT IS
THE TRUTH.
>> YEAH.
BROOKE, I'M SURE THE SAME
SENTIMENT AS YOU'RE WALKING
AROUND, BROOKE, YOU HAD A VERY
MOVING PIECE WITH SOME OF THE
RESCUE WORKERS AND YOU SEE
THESE, AS I'VE BEEN SAYING,
THESE BIG LUG OF A GUY WILL COME
UP TO YOU AND SAY, OH, MY GOD,
AND BARELY GET THEIR WORDS OUT
AND THEY START CRYING.
>> A LOT OF THEM DON'T WANT TO
TALK ABOUT IT RIGHT NOW.
I'M NOT GOING TO FORCE WORDS OUT
OF THEM RIGHT NOW.
IT IS DIFFICULT FOR THEM.
I FLEW BACK THIS MORNING, SPENT
DINNER TIME WITH TWO VOLUNTEER
FIREFIGHTERS ACTUALLY WHO, YOU
KNOW, FRIDAY MORNING, THEY WERE
IN THEIR DAY JOB MODE, HEARD
WHAT HAPPENED, CALL CAME IN AND
WENT INTO FIREFIGHTER MODE.
ROB AND RAY.
THEY SERVED THE COMMUNITY IN
NEWTOWN FOR MORE THAN 20 YEARS
EACH.
BUT THE MORNING THEY GOT THE
CALL, THEY SAID NOTHING,
NOTHING, NOTHING COULD HAVE
PREPARED THEM FOR WHAT THEY SAW.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU ALL BEEN
VOLUNTEERING AS FIREFIGHTERS?
>> I'VE GOT 21 YEARS IN.
>> ALMOST 25.
>> AND WHERE WERE YOU FRIDAY?
>> I WAS WORKING PROBABLY ABOUT
2,000 FEET FROM THE SCHOOL, ON A
STONE WALL, IN THE BUSINESS
DISTRICT IN THE CENTER OF SANDY
HOOK.
SO MY RESPONSE TIME WAS VERY
QUICK.
I WAS THERE VERY SOON.
>> SO YOU WERE THERE.
>> MM-HMM.
>> DID YOU HAVE ANY IDEA WHAT
YOU WERE WALKING INTO?
>> NO.
>> NOT AT ALL.
MATTER OF FACT, WE WERE JUST
TALKING ABOUT THAT, WE HAD A
FIRE CALL A FEW MINUTES AGO, AND
WE WERE TALKING ABOUT THAT ON
THE WAY BACK, AND WE WERE -- YOU
GET THE INITIAL DISPATCH AND YOU
REALLY DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU'RE
COMING INTO.
BUT FOR THE MOST PART, YOU'RE
READY FOR IT.
AND THIS TIME, THAT'S NOT THE
CASE.
>> YOU'RE NEVER READY FOR THIS.
>> NO.
NOBODY -- I DON'T THINK ANYBODY,
ANYBODY ANYWHERE, IF THEY TELL
YOU THEY'RE READY FOR SOMETHING
LIKE THIS, THEY'RE NOT BEING
HONEST WITH YOU.
>> DON'T WANT TO GET INTO
SPECIFICS, BUT HELP US
UNDERSTAND IN THE SCHOOL, WERE
PEOPLE PANICKED, WERE THEY
SCREAMING, WERE THEY RUNNING?
WHAT DID YOU SEE?
>> VERY CHAOTIC AND VERY
EMOTIONAL PROBABLY THE BEST WAY
TO DESCRIBE IT.
>> KIDS EMOTIONAL.
TEACHERS EMOTIONAL.
>> EVERYBODY WAS EMOTIONAL.
>> WHAT WERE THEY SAYING?
>> THE LAW ENFORCEMENT WAS
PRETTY EMOTIONAL.
IT WAS EVERYBODY.
THIS AFFECTED EVERY SINGLE
PERSON THAT WAS THERE.
IMMEDIATELY.
IT WAS, YOU KNOW, IT WAS -- I
SHOULDN'T SAY IMMEDIATELY, VERY
EARLY ON.
IT WAS DETERMINED THAT THIS WAS
BAD, REALLY, REALLY BAD.
>> I ASKED THEM ABOUT A COUPLE
OF THINGS AND ONE THING I ASKED
IS WHAT WAS THAT ONE MOMENT THAT
IS REALLY SEARED INTO THEIR
MEMORIES AND THEY TOLD ME, LIKE
SO MANY PEOPLE DID, IT IS THE
PARENTS.
IT WAS THE PARENTS, THE MOMS AND
DADS WAITING FRIDAY MORNING,
WAITING FOR THEIR CHILDREN, THE
CHILDREN WHO WOULD NOT BE COMING
HOME.
>> AS THE CHILDREN WERE COMING
DOWN THE STREET, LITTLE BY
LITTLE, CLASSROOM BY CLASSROOM,
HOWEVER THEY WERE DOING IT, ALL
HOLDING HANDS, PARENTS WERE
CLAIMING, YOU KNOW, THEIR
CHILDREN.
AFTER A LITTLE WHILE, ONCE THEY
CLAIMED THEIR KID AND SIGNED
THEM OUT, I'M NOT EXACTLY SURE
HOW THEY WORKED IT, BUT THEY
LEFT.
THE ONES THAT DIDN'T, YOU KNOW,
YOU NOTICED THERE IS SOME THAT
ARE STILL STICKING AROUND.
AND THAT'S WHEN YOU REALIZED
THEY'RE PROBABLY NOT GOING TO BE
LEAVING.
THEY'RE GOING TO GET THE
CONFIRMATION SOON ENOUGH THAT,
YOU KNOW, THEY'RE NOT GOING TO
BE GRABBING THEIR CHILD AND
HUGGING THEM AND TAKING THEM
HOME.
THEIR LIFE HAS CHANGED FOREVER.
>> YOU REALIZED THAT IN THAT
MOMENT?
>> YEAH.
THAT WAS SOMETHING THAT, LIKE I
SAID, A COUPLE OF TIMES, WE HAD
TO GO BACK DOWN TO THAT STAGING
AREA AND, YOU KNOW, YOU LOOK
AROUND AND YOU MAKE SURE THERE
IS NOBODY ELSE IN DISTRESS, THAT
MIGHT NEED ASSISTANCE, AND YOU
NOTICE THIS, YOU KNOW, PARENTS
AND RIGHT THERE IN THE FRONT OF
THE LINE FOR TWO HOURS NOW, AND
THERE IS NO MORE KIDS AROUND TO
TAKE HOME.
AND, YOU KNOW, YOU KNOW THIS IS
BAD.
THEY'RE GOING TO GET SOME BAD
NEWS.
AND I'M SURE THAT THEY AT THAT
POINT KNEW IT, BUT THERE IS THAT
SHRED OF HOPE THAT THERE IS
SOMEBODY HIDING IN A CLOSET OR,
YOU KNOW, THEY MISSED.
BUT ULTIMATELY THAT WASN'T THE
CASE.
>> SO MUCH OF THE INTERVIEW TOOK
ON SUCH A SOMBER TONE, BUT A
LITTLE LATER IN THE HOUR, I HAVE
SOMETHING THAT WILL MAKE YOU
SMILE.
I PROMISE.
BECAUSE THEY WERE JOKING AS
FIREFIGHTERS TRY TO USE HUMOR,
RIGHT, TO COPE, THEY WERE
TALKING ABOUT HOW PART OF THEIR
JOB DESCRIPTION IS DELIVERING
TRUCK LOADS OF TEDDY BEARS
THANKS TO FIREHOUSES ACROSS THE
COUNTRY.
WE'LL SHARE THAT MOMENT IN THE
INTERVIEW WITH YOU IN A MATTER
OF MINUTES.
A LOT OF YOU ARE WONDERING HOW
CAN YOU HELP?
HOW CAN YOU HELP THE PEOPLE
AFFECTED IN NEWTOWN?
YOU CAN.
CNN HAS BASICALLY COMPILED THIS
LIST OF CHARITABLE
ORGANIZATIONS, SO ALL YOU HAVE
TO DO IS GO TO THIS WEBSITE, GO
TO CNN.COM/IMPACT AND YOU TOO
CAN HELP.
DON LEMON, BACK TO YOU IN
NEWTOWN.
>> HEY, BROOKE.
YOU AND I HAVE BEEN TALKING
ABOUT GUNS AND GUNMAKERS.
GUNMAKERS STOCKS ARE PLUMMETING
TODAY, TUMBLING AS BIG RETAILER
ARE PULLING RIFLES OFF THE
SHELVES.
WE'LL GO TO THE NEW YORK STOCK
EXCHANGE AFTER THIS BREAK.
[ Male Announcer ]
RED LOBSTER'S CRABFEST
ENDS SOON.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OUR TENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
ANY TREE ON THIS LOT
IS ON ME.
I'M THE MESSENGER,
BY THE WAY.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
JOANNE.
WITH THE HUNDREDS THAT I SAVE
WITH PROGRESSIVE
ON MY CAR INSURANCE,
THIS TREE IS ON ME.
NO WAY.
WAY.
THIS TREE IS ON ME.
REALLY?!
YES.
AAH!
LET ME JUST TRIM IT UP
A LITTLE BIT FOR YOU.
[ buzzing ]
THANK YOU.
SAVING'S GREETINGS.
YOU GUYS ARE GONNA GET THIS TREE
RIGHT HERE?
ARE YOU SURE
THAT'S THE ONE?
I'LL TIE IT TO THE ROOF
FOR YOU.
MAKE SAVINGS
A NEW HOLIDAY TRADITION.
♪
♪ HARK HOW THE BELLS,
SWEET SILVER BELLS ♪
♪ ALL SEEM TO SAY
THROW CARE AWAY ♪
♪ FROM EVERYWHERE,
FILLING THE AIR ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
CHEX PARTY MIX.
EASY 15-MINUTE
HOMEMADE RECIPES
YOU JUST POP IN A MICROWAVE.
LIKE CARAMEL CHOCOLATE
DRIZZLES.
HAPPIER HOLIDAYS.
CHEX PARTY MIX.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME FOR CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN DIARRHEA HITS,
KAOPECTATE STOPS IT FAST.
POWERFUL LIQUID RELIEF
SPEEDS TO THE SOURCE.
FAST.
[ Male Announcer ]
STOP THE UH-OH FAST
WITH KAOPECTATE.
>>> THE NEWEST CHAPTER IN THE
OLD DEBATE OVER GUNS JUST
GETTING STARTED.
TODAY IN WASHINGTON WE HEARD
MORE VOICES SPEAKING OUT HERE.
THE BRADY CAMPAIGN TO PREVENT
GUN VIOLENCE, THEY HELD A NEWS
CONFERENCE FEATURING FAMILIES
WHO LOST LOVED ONES IN MASS
SHOOTINGS, INCLUDING THE FATHER
WHO LOST HIS SON AT COLUMBINE
HIGH SCHOOL.
>> THESE PEOPLE HERE BEFORE YOU,
BECAUSE THEY REFUSE TO BE
STATISTICS.
THEY WANT TO BE THE STORIES, THE
STORIES OF ORDINARY AMERICANS
WHO HAVE BEEN THROUGH THE --
THEY HAVE BEEN THROUGH HELL AND
BACK.
AND THEY DON'T WANT IT TO HAPPEN
TO THE REST OF YOU.
>> AT THE U.S. CAPITAL,
REPUBLICAN LAWMAKER CAME OUT OF
A MEETING WITH HOUSE SPEAKER
JOHN BOEHNER, SAID HE IS READY
FOR SERIOUS DISCUSSIONS ON GUNS.
>> THE SPEAKER SAID, LOOK, THIS
IS -- THIS IS AN OBVIOUSLY
HORRIBLE EVENT THAT TOUCHED
EVERYONE IN THE COUNTRY AND
CERTAINLY DEVASTATED THE
COMMUNITY.
WE NEED TO BE RESPECTFUL.
WE NEED TO BE DIPLOMATIC IN OUR
REMARKS, REMARKS LIKE, WELL, WE
SHOULD JUST ARM THE PRINCIPALS
AND TEACHERS ARE PROBABLY NOT
APPROPRIATE.
AND THAT WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO
NEXT YEAR ENGAGE IN A DISCUSSION
ABOUT WHAT IS APPROPRIATE.
>> INCLUDED HERE TODAY, TEXAS
GOVERNOR RICK PERRY, HE'S
WEIGHING IN ON ALL OF THIS AT A
TEA PARTY EVENT JUST YESTERDAY.
HE CAME DOWN IN FAVOR OF THE
RIGHT TO CARRY A LEGALLY
PURCHASED CONCEALED WEAPON
THROUGHOUT THE STATE OF TEXAS.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> IF YOU GO THROUGH THE
PROCESS, AND YOU HAVE BEEN
DUALLY BACKGROUNDED AND TRAINED
AND YOU ARE A CONCEALED HANDGUN
LICENSED CARRYING INDIVIDUAL,
YOU SHOULD BE ABLE TO CARRY YOUR
HANDGUN ANYWHERE IN THIS STATE.
>> WE'RE LEARNING TODAY THAT THE
INVESTORS WHO OWN THE COMPANY
THAT MAKES THAT BUSHMASTER RIFLE
USED IN CONNECTICUT, THEY WANT
TO DUMP THEIR INVESTMENT.
THIS IS AN UNUSUAL MOVE IN A
HIGHLY PROFITABLE INDUSTRY WHERE
PUBLIC OPINION RARELY AFFECTS
BUSINESS DECISIONS.
CHRISTINE ROMANS, LET ME BRING
YOU IN HERE.
AND JUST TELL ME WHY THIS -- WHY
DOESN'T BUSHMASTER'S PARENT
COMPANY, WHY DON'T THEY WANT TO
OWN THIS GUNMAKER ANYMORE?
>> THEY SAY THIS IS A WATER SHED
EVENT AND THERE WILL BE A
DIFFERENCE IN THE WAY THE NATION
FEELS ABOUT THE GUNMAKERS.
PRIVATE EQUITY INVESTORS WILL
SELL THE COMPANY.
BUSHMASTER MANUFACTURED THAT GUN
USED TO KILL THE TEACHERS AND
CHILDREN IN CONNECTICUT AND NOW
IT SAYS, IT IS APPARENT THAT THE
SANDY HOOK TRAGEDY WAS A WATER
SHED EVENT THAT RAISED THE
NATIONAL DEBATE ON GUN CONTROL
TO AN UNPRECEDENTED LEVEL.
IT IS NOT OUR ROLE TO TAKE
POSITIONS OR ATTEMPT TO SHAPE OR
INFLUENCE THE GUN CONTROL POLICY
DEBATE, THERE ARE, HOWEVER,
ACTIONS THAT WE AS A FIRM CAN
TAKE.
LET ME TELL YOU THIS, BROOKE,
MAKING GUNS AND AMMUNITION IS
QUITE PROFITABLE.
BUSHMASTER'S PARENT COMPANY IS A
COLLECTION OF TEN GUN AND AMMO
MAKERS, EARNED $232 MILLION
PROFIT LAST YEAR.
THESE ARE THE FASTEST GROWING
PARTS OF THE GUN MARKET AND, BY
THE WAY, THE RIFLES THAT
BUSHMASTER MAKES, THEY'RE ALSO
THE PREFERRED WEAPON OF MEXICAN
DRUG CARTELS.
ONE OF THE PREFERRED WEAPONS.
IT IS RARE FOR A PRIVATE EQUITY
TO DUMP OUT OF AN INVESTMENT
LIKE THIS, BROOKE, BUT TODAY,
CERBERUS IS SAYING THEY WILL
SELL BUSHMASTER, THE PARENT
COMPANY THAT MADE THAT GUN.
>> THIS IS THE MILITARY-STYLE
RIFLE, ONE OF SEVERAL THAT THE
SHOOTER HAD FRIDAY, KILLING THE
STUDENTS, KILLING THE TEACHERS
AND IN A TWIST HERE, IT TURNS
OUT THE CALIFORNIA TEACHERS,
THEY'RE INVESTORS IN BUSHMASTER,
RIGHT?
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
IT IS TRUE.
THE CALIFORNIA STATE TEACHERS
RETIREMENT SYSTEM INVESTED
MILLIONS OF DOLLARS IN CERBERUS.
CERBERUS FORMED FREEDOM GROUP,
THE GROUP OF TEN COMPANIES
INCLUDING BUSHMASTER, OTHER AMMO
AND ACCESSORYMAKERS TOO, VEST
MAKERS, THAT MEANS LOOK AT THE
FLOW OF MONEY.
THAT MEANS CALIFORNIA TEACHERS
RETIREMENT FUND OWN 2ZS 2.4% OFE
FREEDOM GROUP.
THEY'RE REVIEWING THAT
INVESTMENT, CALIFORNIA IS
REVIEWING THAT INVESTMENT, THE
CALIFORNIA TREASURER WANTS TO
MAKE SURE THERE ARE NO PUBLIC
SECTOR WORKERS MONEY THAT IS
SITTING THERE IN INVESTMENTS IN
GUNS.
BUT, CLEARLY, THE OPTICS OF A
TEACHERS RETIREMENT FUND
INVESTING IN A COMPANY THAT
MAKES A PRODUCT THAT WAS USED TO
KILL STUDENTS AND TEACHERS, THE
OPTICS ARE PRETTY DIFFICULT.
WE'RE ALSO TOLD RIGHT NOW AS
WELL THAT THE NEW YORK COMPTR  L
COMPTROLLER, NEW YORK STATE HAS
INVESTMENTS IN THE GUNMAKER
STURM AND LUGER.
>> CHRISTINE ROMANS, THANK YOU
SO MUCH FOR US IN NEW YORK.
BACK TO NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
AND DON LEMON.
DON?
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH, BROOKE.
YOU KNOW, TWO OF THE BIGGEST
RETAILERS, BIGGEST RETAILERS
REACTING BY PULLING SOME OF
THEIR GUNS OFF THE SHELVES AND
OFF THEIR WEBSITES AS WELL.
I'M SURE THAT'S AFFECTING
STOCKS.
TO ALISON KOSIK AT THE NEW YORK
STOCK EXCHANGE.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
>> WE'RE TALKING ABOUT DICK'S
SPORTING GOODS.
IT IS REMOVING -- IT REMOVED ALL
THE GUNS FROM ITS STORE THAT IS
CLOSEST TO NEWTOWN WHERE YOU
ARE.
AND IT IS SUSPENDING THE SALE OF
CERTAIN KINDS OF SEMI-AUTOMATIC
RIFLES FROM ITS STORES THAT ARE
ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
THE RETAILER SAYS WHAT THIS IS
IS A SHOW OF RESPECT DURING THIS
TIME OF NATIONAL MOURNING.
OVER AT WALMART, THEY'RE NO
LONGER ADVERTISING THE
BUSHMASTER AR-15, THAT'S THE ONE
USED IN THE NEWTOWN SHOOTING.
THEY'RE NO LONGER ADVERTISING
THAT WEAPON ON THE WEB.
BUT WHAT WALMART DOES SAY IS YOU
CAN STILL BUY IT AT SELECT
LOCATIONS.
KEEP IN MIND, WALMART IS ONE OF
THE BIGGEST GUN DEALERS IN THE
WORLD.
AND HIGH CAPACITY MAGAZINES AND
GUNS LIKE SEMI-AUTOMATIC
MILITARY STYLE RIFLES, THEY ARE
THE FASTEST GROWING PART OF THE
MARKET.
JUST LOOKING AT WALMART'S
WEBSITE, THERE ARE HUNDREDS OF
WEAPONS LISTED ON THERE.
THE BUSHMASTER AR-15 IS NO
LONGER LISTED ON BASS PRO SHOP'S
SITE EITHER BUT YOU CAN VIEW IT
ON CABELLIAS.
RETAILERS WANTING TO DISTANCE
THEMSELVES FROM THE TRAGEDY AND
THAT'S WHY THEY'RE MAKING THE
CHANGES, DON.
>> ALLISON, GUNMAKER STOCKS
TUMBLING TODAY?
>> THEY ARE.
WE'RE SEEING SEVERAL SHARES
FALLING.
GUN STOCKS.
ANYWHERE FROM 8% TO 10%.
THE BIG WORRY HERE IS THAT NOT
ONLY WILL YOU SEE BIG
REGULATIONS GO ON GUNS, BUT
PEOPLE WILL START TO SHY AWAY
FROM BUYING THEM AS WELL.
AS FAR AS INVESTORS FEEL AS FAR
AS BECAUSE OF THE TRAGEDY THAT
HAPPENED.
YOU LOOK AT SMITH & WESSON,
STURM RUGER & COMPANY, THE
SHARES ARE FALLING AGAIN TODAY.
SOMETHING SO CONTROVERSIAL,
ESPECIALLY AT A TIME LIKE THIS,
YOUINVESTORS GOING TO
THOSE COMPANIES TO BUY, YOU SEE
THEM GETTING OUT.
>> ALISON KOSIK AT THE NEW YORK
STOCK EXCHANGE, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
>>> BACK TO MY COLLEAGUE NOW,
BROOKE BALDWIN IN ATLANTA.
BROOKE, I THINK THIS IS -- THIS
IS AN INTERESTING WATER SHED
MOMENT WHEN IT COMES TO GUNS IN
THIS COUNTRY, GUN LEGISLATION.
DON'T KNOW WHICH WAY IT IS GOING
TO TURN OUT, BUT IT IS SOMETHING
INTERESTING TO WATCH OVER THE
NEXT FEW MONTHS AND NEXT FEW
DAYS AND MONTHS.
>> AGREED.
DON LEMON, WE'LL COME BACK TO
YOU MOMENTARILY.
WANT TO COVER OTHER NEWS HERE
INCLUDING THIS TERRIFYING,
ABSOLUTELY TERRIFYING ORDEAL
HERE.
FIVE DAYS AFTER THE CAPTURE, AN
AMERICAN JOURNALIST AND HIS
PRODUCTION CREW, THEY ARE OUT
SAFELY OF SYRIA.
TODAY, THE JOURNALISTS SPOKE OF
THIS ORDEAL.
YOU'LL HEAR IT IN HIS OWN WORDS
NEXT.
TONIGHT OUR GUEST,
THOMAS SARGENT.
NOBEL LAUREATE
IN ECONOMICS,
AND ONE OF THE MOST CITED
ECONOMISTS IN THE WORLD.
PROFESSOR SARGENT,
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT CD RATES WILL
BE IN TWO YEARS?
NO.
IF HE CAN'T, NO ONE CAN.
THAT'S WHY ALLY HAS
A RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
ALLY BANK.
YOUR MONEY NEEDS AN ALLY.
>>> RICHARD ENGLE, THE CHIEF
FOREIGN CORRESPONDENT FOR NBC
NEWS AND HIS PRODUCTION CREW,
THEY ARE FREE TODAY.
THEY'RE FREE, THOUGH, AFTER
BEING HELD FOR FIVE DAYS INSIDE
OF SYRIA.
ENGLE SPOKE WITH REPORTERS IN
TURKEY SHORTLY AFTER HE AND HIS
TEAM ESCAPED DURING A DEADLY
FIRE FIGHT BETWEEN THEIR
KIDNAPPERS AND SYRIAN REBELS.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> THE LAST FIVE DAYS WERE VERY
DIFFICULT.
WE'RE VERY HAPPY TO BE OUT.
WE'RE VERY HAPPY TO BE BACK IN
TURKEY.
WE LOVE BEING HERE, WE LOVE THIS
COUNTRY.
WE APPRECIATE ALL THE HELP.
THE LAST FIVE DAYS ARE SOME DAYS
THAT WE WOULD RATHER FORGET.
>> WANT TO BRING IN HALA GORANI
FROM WASHINGTON.
AND BUNCH OF QUESTIONS FOR YOU.
FIRST, WHEN DID ENGEL AND HIS
TEAM GO MISSING AND DO WE KNOW
WHO HIS KIDNAPPERS WERE?
>> WE HEARD FROM HIM DIRECTLY A
FEW HOURS AGO.
HE WAS ACTUALLY ABLE TO SPEAK
LIVE WITH HIS COLLEAGUES IN NEW
YORK ON THE "TODAY" SHOW.
WE GOT A SENSE OF WHAT HAPPENED
TO HIM, WHAT MUST HAVE BEEN AN
EXTREMELY TERRIFYING ORDEAL FOR
THEM.
THEY WERE IN NORTHWESTERN SYRIA,
TRAVELING WITH REBELS.
AT ONE POINT MORE THAN A DOZEN
ARMED GUNMEN, RICHARD ENGEL,
SAID AMBUSHED THEM AND TOOK THEM
INTO CUSTODY, THREW THEM IN THE
BACK OF A PICKUP TRUCK AND DROVE
THEM TO A LOCATION.
THEY WERE BLINDFOLDED.
THEY WERE BOUND FOR SEVERAL
DAYS.
THEY WERE SUBJECTED TO MOCK
EXECUTIONS.
THEY WENT THROUGH REALLY A
TERRIBLE TIME.
AND THIS IS PART OF WHAT RICHARD
TOLD HIS COLLEAGUES ON THE
"TODAY" SHOW, A FEW HOURS AGO,
ABOUT WHAT THEY WENT THROUGH
WHILE THEY WERE IN CAPTIVITY.
LET'S LISTEN.
>> AND THEY TOOK US TO A SERIES
OF SAFE HOUSES AND INTERROGATION
PLACES.
AND THEY KEPT US BLINDFOLDED,
BOUND.
WE WEREN'T PHYSICALLY BEATEN OR
TORTURED.
IT WAS A LOT OF PSYCHOLOGICAL
TORTURE.
THREATS OF BEING KILLED.
THEY MADE US CHOOSE WHICH ONE OF
US WOULD BE SHOT FIRST.
WHEN WE REFUSED, THERE WERE MOCK
SHOOTINGS.
THEY PRETENDED TO SHOOT GHAZI
SEVERAL TIMES.
WHEN YOU'RE BLINDFOLDED, AND
THEN THEY FIRED THE GUN UP IN
THE AIR.
IT CAN BE VERY TRAUMATIC
EXPERIENCE.
AND AT END OF THIS, WE WERE
BEING MOVED TO YET ANOTHER
LOCATION IN THE -- AROUND 11:00
LAST NIGHT LOCAL TIME.
AND AS WE WERE MOVING ALONG THE
ROAD, THE KIDNAPPERS CAME ACROSS
A REBEL CHECKPOINT.
SOMETHING THEY HADN'T EXPECTED.
AND SO WE WERE IN THE BACK OF,
LIKE, WHEN YOU THINK OF AS A
MINIVAN, AND AS WE WERE DRIVING
ALONG THE ROAD, THE KIDNAPPERS
SAW THIS CHECKPOINT, STARTED A
GUNFIGHT WITH IT, TWO OF THE
KIDNAPPERS WERE KILLED, WE
CLIMBED OUT OF THE VEHICLE AND
THE REBELS TOOK US.
WE SPENT THE NIGHT WITH THEM.
WE DIDN'T GET MUCH SLEEP.
>> WELL, BROOKE, YOU HEARD IT
THERE.
ESSENTIALLY THEY WERE -- THEY
WERE RESCUED BY REBELS, CLOSE TO
THE SYRIAN REGIME.
THIS IS AN UNBELIEVABLY LUCKY
ESCAPE.
LET'S BE HONEST HERE.
IT COULD HAVE GONE HORRIBLY
WRONG, A MILLION DIFFERENT WAYS,
HELD CAPTIVE, KIDNAPPED, IN A
HOUSE, TRANSPORTED TO A SECOND
LOCATION.
AT THAT POINT, RUNNING INTO A
REBEL CHECKPOINT COMPLETELY BY
ACCIDENT.
AND GETTING INTO A GUNFIGHT
WHERE TWO OF THE KIDNAPPERS ARE
KILLED AND YET RICHARD ENGEL AND
HIS CREW ARE ABLE TO GET OUT.
I WANT TO TELL OUR VIEWERS ABOUT
WHO RICHARD SAYS HE BELIEVES
WERE HIS KIDNAPPERS.
BECAUSE FOR SEVERAL DAYS,
BROOKE, WE THOUGHT ESSENTIALLY
PERHAPS IT WAS A REBEL UNIT, A
JIHADI UNIIT.
HE BELIE
HE BELIEVES IT IS THE PRO
GOVERNMENT MILITIA, WHO ARE
REALLY MAKING NO SECRET OF THEIR
SYMPATHY FOR THE GOVERNMENT OF
BASHAR AL ASSAD.
AND THIS IS YET ANOTHER LAYER OF
DANGER TO REPORTING OUT OF THAT
COUNTRY.
>> JUST TO BE BLINDFOLDED, TO
THINK YOU'RE BEING EXECUTED
MULTIPLE TIMES AND NOT
HAPPENING, THEY ESCAPE.
IT IS A TERRIFYING ORDEAL AND
UNDERSCORES THAT REALLY, YOU
KNOW, THESE CORRESPONDENTS AND
THE CREW S AND RADIO AND TV AND
THE WRITERS, EVERYONE RISKING
THEIR LIVES TO GET INTO SYRIA TO
TELL THE STORY OF THE SYRIANS
BEING SLAUGHTERED MONTH AFTER
MONTH.
>> AND THERE ARE MORE IN
CAPTIVITY AND ORDINARY SEERIANS
BEING SUBJECTED TO KIDNAPPINGS
FOR RANSOM.
THE SITUATION IS DETERIORATING
RAPIDLY.
>> HALA GORANI, THANK YOU SO
MUCH.
WE'LL STAY ON IT AND WATCH WHAT
HAPPENS IN SYRIA.
>>> ONE MAN ACROSS THE UNITED
STATES FOUND A UNIQUE WAY TO
HONOR THE VICTIMS IN NEWTOWN.
YOU'LL MEET HIM NEXT.
Wooohooo....Hahaahahaha!
Oh...there you go.
I'm gonna stand
up to her!
No you're not.
I know.
You know Ronny folks who save
hundreds of dollars
switching to GEICO
sure are happy.
How happy are they Jimmy?
Happier than a witch in
a broom factory.
Get happy. Get GEICO.
Fifteen minutes could save you
fifteen percent or more.
TO THE BEST VACATION
SP(ALL) THE GULF!
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHICH OF
OUR GREAT STATES FOLKS VISIT.
MISSISSIPPI,
ALABAMA,
LOUISIANA
OR FLORIDA,
THEY'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
SHAUL, YOUR ALABAMA
HOSPITALITY IS INCREDIBLE.
THANKS, KAREN.
LOVE YOUR MISSISSIPPI OUTDOORS.
I VOTE FOR YOUR
FLORIDA BEACHES, DAWN.
BILL, THIS LOUISIANA
SEAFOOD IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR ON THE GULF,
WE'VE DECIDED TO PUT
ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
NOW IS THE PERFECT TIME TO
VISIT ANYONE OF OUR STATES.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE, GO FISHING
OR JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
WE'VE GOT COASTLINE TO EXPLORE
AND WILDLIFE TO PHOTOGRAPH.
AND THERE'S WORLD CLASS DINING
WITH OUR WORLD FAMOUS SEAFOOD.
SO FOR A GREAT VACATION
THIS YEAR, COME TO THE GULF.
ITS ALL FABULOUS BUT
I GIVE FLORIDA THE EDGE.
RIGHT AFTER MISSISSIPPI.
YOU MEAN ALABAMA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
THIS INVITATION IS
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP
AND ALL OF US WHO
CALL THE GULF HOME.
>>> "THE SITUATION ROOM" WITH
WOLF BLITZER COMING UP AT THE
TOP OF THE HOUR.
>> I WENT OVER TO THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
HEADQUARTERS 45 MINUTES OR SO,
ARRIVED FROM WHERE WE ARE HERE
IN NEWTOWN.
I HAD A CHANCE TO SPEAK TO
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE.
HE'S BECOME THE FACE OF THIS
INVESTIGATION.
HE'S BEEN DOING DAILY BRIEFINGS.
DOESN'T DO THEM ANYMORE, HE
WANTS TO HOLD BACK A LITTLE BIT.
I DID GO TO HIS OFFICE.
WE HAD A CHANCE TO SIT DOWN IN
HIS OFFICE, TALK ABOUT WHAT'S
GOING ON.
I ASKED HIM SOME SENSITIVE
QUESTIONS, WE WALKED AROUND A
LITTLE BIT, CONTINUED THE
CONVERSATION, HOW THIS IS
AFFECTING HIM PERSONALLY.
LISTEN TO THIS ONE EXCHANGE.
WAS THERE ONE MOMENT THAT STANDS
OUT IN YOUR MIND THAT YOU'LL
NEVER FORGET THE REST OF YOUR
LIFE?
>> I THINK THE CRIME SCENE
ITSELF IS SOMETHING THAT HAS
MADE AN INDELIBLE MARK IN ALL OF
OUR MINDS.
IT IS SOMETHING THAT YOU'LL
NEVER BE ABLE TO FORGET.
>> SOUNDS LIKE IT IS WEIGHING ON
HIM.
>> THAT CRIME SCENE.
WHEN HE WENT INTO THAT SCHOOL,
THAT ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, AND SAW
WHAT HAD HAPPENED, MOMENTS AFTER
IT OCCURRED, AND HE SAW THOSE
BODIES OF THE YOUNG KIDS, SAW
THE TEACHERS, HE SAYS IN ALL OF
THE 39 YEARS HE'S BEEN A POLICE
OFFICER, LAW ENFORCEMENT, STATE
TROOPER, HE'S NEVER SEEN
ANYTHING LIKE THAT AND IT WILL
WEIGH WITH HIM FOR THE REST OF
HIS LIFE.
LIKE EVERYONE.
HE'S BEEN MOVED.
AND HE ALSO TOLD ME SOMETHING I
DIDN'T KNOW, I DON'T KNOW IF YOU
KNEW THIS, BUT THE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE, THEY ASSIGNED A
TROOPER, ONE TROOPER TO EACH
FAMILY OF THE 26, SO THAT THAT
TROOPER WILL PROVIDE
INFORMATION, FOLKS WON'T HAVE TO
LEARN SENSITIVE INFORMATION FROM
THE MEDIA, FOR EXAMPLE, THEY'LL
BE BRIEFED AND THEY'LL HAVE A
CHANCE TO TALK TO SOMEONE.
I THINK IT IS GOING TO BE
IMPORTANT, LOOK, YOU'LL NEVER
GET OVER THIS IF YOU'RE A
SURVIVING FAMILY OF WHAT
HAPPENED, BUT THEY'RE DOING THE
BEST THEY CAN.
>> I WAS TELLING KATE, LISTEN,
THE FAMILIES ARE JUST DEALING
WITH TREMENDOUS PAIN RIGHT NOW.
AND JOURNALISTS, PEOPLE COVERING
IT, THE RESCUE WORKERS, WE'RE
NOT DEALING WITH ANYTHING LIKE
THAT.
BUT JUST LIKE TO BE TRANSPARENT
IN ALL HONESTY, YOU WERE KIND
ENOUGH, BECAUSE YOU KNEW LAST
NIGHT THAT WE WERE ALL AFFECTED
BY THIS AND YOU TOOK A BUNCH OF
US OUT TO DINNER LAST NIGHT TO
GIVE US A BRIEF MOMENT TO TALK
ABOUT IT AND TO SIT DOWN WITH
EACH OTHER AND COMMUNE AND THAT
REALLY HELPED, JUST TALKING
ABOUT IT.
>> IT HAS BEEN TOUGH ON NOT ONLY
THE FOLKS HERE AND THIS
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE COMMUNITY, BUT
TOUGH ON EVERYBODY.
LAW ENFORCEMENT, OBVIOUSLY THE
FAMILIES, TOUGHEST ON THEM.
AND I CAN'T EVEN BEGIN TO THINK
WHAT THEY'RE GOING THROUGH.
EVERYBODY HAS BEEN AFFECTED.
ALL OF US WILL BE AFFECTED THE
REST OF OUR LIVES BY WHAT WE
HAVE SEEN.
>> YOU'VE BEEN IN WAR ZONES
BEFORE.
I'VE COVERED SOME REALLY
HORRIFIC STORIES.
NATURAL DISASTERS, WHATEVER.
BUT WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT 20
LITTLE, REALLY BABIES, KIDS, HOW
DOES THAT --
>> YOU SEE THE LITTLE PICTURES
OF THOSE KIDS, YOU KNOW, I CAN'T
EVEN LOOK ANYMORE.
IT IS SO HARD.
>> A SCHOOL BUS WENT BY AND WE
SAW KIDS ON IT AND ONE OF THE
KIDS IN THE FRONT CRYING, JUST A
MOMENT AGO, AND AS A SCHOOL BUS
IS GOING BY, THE MOVING TRUCKS
WITH THEIR THINGS TO TAKE TO THE
OTHER SCHOOL GOING IN THE
OPPOSITE DIRECTION, AND SAME
THING WITH THE FUNERAL
PROCESSION, MOVING TRUCKS GOING
BY THE OPPOSITE DIRECTION.
>> LITTLE WHITE COFFINS, YOU
KNOW, THAT ARE BURYING THESE
KIDS.
IT IS AWFUL.
>> IT IS.
>> BROOKE, WE'LL TOSS IT BACK TO
YOU.
YOU SAW SOME OF IT, THE FIRST
TWO FUNERALS WERE YESTERDAY AND
YOU WERE HERE FOR THAT AS WELL.
YOU SAW SOME OF THE PROCESSIONS.
THERE IS NO OTHER WAY TO
DESCRIBE IT, HORRIFIC, HEART
BREAKING.
>> IT IS.
NOT TOO FAR FROM WHERE YOU TWO
WERE STANDING, I SORT OF BUMPED
INTO THIS FIRST RESPONDER, HE
HAD BEEN A FIREFIGHTER WITH
SANDY HOOK SINCE HIGH SKOOCH.
I STARTED TALKING TO THEM.
THEY HAD BOX AFTER BOX AFTER BOX
THEY WERE OPENING.
INSIDE ALL THESE BOXES, THESE
CARDBOARD BOXES WERE WREATHS.
26 OF THEM, ALL DELIVERED TO THE
FIREHOUSE IN SANDY HOOK, BY A
STRANGER.
WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF THE WREATHS?
JUST PEOPLE YOU DON'T KNOW,
SENDING YOU ALL THESE WREATHS TO
PUT UP IN YOUR TOWN?
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY TO THE PEOPLE
OF PORTLAND, OREGON?
>> THANK YOU.
IT MAKES US FEEL WARM TO KNOW
THIS IS -- IT IS AMAZING THAT
PEOPLE THAT FAR AWAY CARE ABOUT
US.
>> WREATHS SENT ALL THE WAY FROM
OREGON.
SO WE ACTUALLY WENT BACK TO
THOSE BOXES THERE, AND THE TOWN
SQUARE, JUST TO SEE WHO WAS THE
KIND SOUL TO SEND THEM.
AND WE FOUND HIM.
HE IS LARRY TWOFIL JOINING ME ON
THE PHONE.
HE OWNS TWOFIL FARM IN OREGON.
LARRY, WHY DID YOU DO IT?
>> IT WASN'T JUST ME.
IT WAS OUR FAMILY, EMPLOYEES, A
GROUP OF US GOT TOGETHER ON
SATURDAY MORNING AFTER WATCHING
THESE EVENTS UNFOLD, AND, YOU
KNOW, JUST REALLY NO WORDS TO
DESCRIBE THIS.
AND WE JUST THOUGHT WE NEEDED TO
SEND A MESSAGE THAT WE WERE
HURTING AND WE KNEW THAT THERE
WAS PEOPLE HURTING THERE.
AND WANTED TO SEND A MESSAGE TO
THE FIRST RESPONDERS AND THE
FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS THAT WE
CARED.
AND OUR FAMILY HAS BEEN MAKING
WREATHS FOR OVER 100 YEARS.
IT IS SOMETHING WE DO, SOMETHING
WE'RE PRETTY GOOD AT.
AND WE FELT THERE WAS A DIRE
NEED TO DO THIS.
SO WE GOT TOGETHER AS A FAMILY,
AS A COMPANY, FIRST THING
SATURDAY MORNING WE WENT TO WORK
ON THIS LITTLE PROJECT AND GOT
IT DONE.
>> DO YOU HAVE FIREFIGHTERS IN
YOUR FAMILY?
HE TOLD ME THAT BASICALLY, YOU
KNOW, IN CAME THIS MASS DELIVERY
FROM U.P.S. OF ALL THESE
WREATHS.
WHAT SPECIFICALLY WAS IT OR
PERHAPS IT WAS NOTHING?
PERHAPS IT WAS SIMPLY THE STORY
THAT TOUCHED YOU SO MUCH.
>> WELL, IT JUST -- JUST REALLY
NO WORDS FOR IT.
WE'RE ALL -- EVERYONE I'VE
TALKED TO IS REALLY HURTING FROM
THIS, THIS TRAGEDY.
AND THERE IT IS SO HARD TO
DESCRIBE, HARD TO IMAGINE.
I HAVE KIDS OF MY OWN.
OUR FAMILY ALL RAISED KIDS IN
SCHOOLS AND JUST -- IT IS JUST
VERY DIFFICULT FOR EVERYONE.
SO WE JUST WANTED TO LET PEOPLE
KNOW THAT WE WERE THINKING OF
THEM AND WE REALLY CARED AND
WANTED TO DO SOMETHING.
SO THAT WAS OUR WAY OF SENDING A
MESSAGE.
>> AND JUST FINALLY, I'M SURE
THE LAST THING YOU INTENDED OR
I'M SURE YOU MEANT TO DO THIS
ANONYMOUSLY AND FORGIVE ME, I
HAPPEN TO BE IN PERHAPS THE
RIGHT SPOT AT THE RIGHT TIME, I
SAW THESE FIREFIGHTERS UNPACKING
THESE WREATHS, AND, YOU KNOW,
AND IN TALKING TO THIS ONE
FIREFIGHTER, YOU KNOW, JUST SO
SIMPLY SAYING THANK YOU, JUST
MAKING HIM SO WARM KNOWING THAT
SOMEONE, ALL THE WAY ACROSS THE
COUNTRY, CARED SO MUCH.
IF ANYONE FROM SANDY HOOK
FIREHOUSE IS LISTENING, WHAT
WOULD YOU WANT THEM TO KNOW?
>> HEY, I JUST THINK WE'RE JUST
LIKE THE WHOLE REST OF THE
COUNTRY.
AND A LOT OF THE WORLD.
WE CARE.
WE DO REALLY CARE ABOUT THEM.
AND, YOU KNOW, THEY'RE IN OUR
THOUGHTS AND PRAYERS AND WE WISH
THEM THE BEST GOING FORWARD.
>> WE JOIN YOU IN THAT SAME
MESSAGE.
LARRY, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
ROLE
THROUGHOUT OUR LIVES.
One A Day Men's 50+
IS A COMPLETE MULTIVITAMIN
DESIGNED FOR MEN'S HEALTH
CONCERNS AS WE AGE.
IT HAS 7 ANTIOXIDANTS
TO SUPPORT CELL HEALTH.
One A Day Men's 50+.
YOU CAN STAY IN
AND SHARE SOMETHING...
OR YOU CAN GET OUT THERE
AND ACTUALLY SHARE SOMETHING.
♪
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
>>> IF TAX RATES RISE FOR THOSE
MAKING MORE THAN $400,000 A
YEAR, THE ECONOMY WILL NOT BE
HURT.
FROM THE CNN MONEY NEWSROOM, I'M
ALI VELSHI.
THIS IS YOUR MONEY.
YOU'RE PAYING LESS FOR GASOLINE,
TOYOTA WILL PAY MORE BECAUSE OF
ANOTHER CAR BLUNDER.
INSTAGRAM INTENDS TO MAKE A BUCK
OFF YOUR PICS AND THE FALLOUT
FROM THE SHOOTING IN CONNECTICUT
IS HURTING GUN MANUFACTURERS.
FIRST, TWO WEEKS TO GO BEFORE
THE COUNTRY FALLS OVER A FISCAL
CLIFF, AND NEGOTIATIONS ARE
PICKING UP STEAM IN WASHINGTON
WITH THREE MEETINGS IN EIGHT
DAYS BETWEEN PRESIDENT OBAMA AND
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER.
THE PRESIDENT HAS BEEN INSISTING
ON LETTING TAXES RISE ON THOSE
MAKING MORE THAN $250,000 A
YEAR.
THE TOP 2% OF EARNERS.
BOEHNER AGREED TO LET TAXES RISE
ON PEOPLE MAKING A MILLION OR
MORE A YEAR AND THE PRESIDENT'S
COUNTEROFFER, RAISE TAXES ON
THOSE MAKING MORE THAN $400,000
A YEAR.
FOR SOME PERSPECTIVE, THE TOP 1%
OF EARNERS IN THE UNITED STATES
MAKE $375,000 OR MORE A YEAR.
>> I THINK WE ALL KNOW THAT
EVERY INCOME TAX FILER IN
AMERICA IS GOING TO PAY A HIGHER
RATE COME JANUARY 1st UNLESS
CONGRESS ACTS.
I BELIEVE IT IS IMPORTANT THAT
WE PROTECT AS MANY AMERICAN
TAXPAYERS AS WE CAN.
AND OUR PLAN B WOULD PROTECT
AMERICAN TAXPAYERS WHO MAKE A
MILLION DOLLARS OR LESS.
AND HAVE ALL OF THEIR CURRENT
RATES EXTENDED.
>> PLAN B IS THE IDEA THAT
THEY'LL PUT THROUGH LEGISLATION.
WHILE SPEAKER BOEHNER SHOULD BE
COMMENDED FOR CONSIDERING TAX
HIKES ON A TOKEN FEW, WHAT
SHOULD WE MAKE OF ARGUMENTS FROM
HIS REPUBLICAN BASE WHICH SAY
ANY TAX HIKE ON THE RICH WILL
HURT THE ECONOMY?
WELL, CONSERVATIVES INSIST THAT
ONCE TAXES ARE RAISED, THE
WEALTHY WON'T USE THEIR
DISPOSABLE INCOME ON SPENDING IN
A WAY THAT STIMULATES THE
ECONOMY.
WE ALL LOSE, THEY SAY, I'VE GOT
NEWS FOR THEM, DOESN'T MATTER
WHETHER YOU RAISE TAXES ON
INCOMES OF A MILLION A YEAR OR
$400,000 A YEAR.
PEOPLE IN THOSE HIGH INCOME
BRACKETS ARE NOT GOING TO PULL
BACK THEIR SPENDING JUST BECAUSE
THEY SEE THEIR MARGINAL TAX
RATES, THE TAXES ON EVERY DOLLAR
ABOVE THE BASE LINE, GO UP BY A
FEW PERCENTAGE POINTS.
THERE IS A CUTOFF POINT BELOW
WHICH WE ALL SPEND THE BULK OF
OUR MONEY ON LIFE'S NECESSARY
SYS.
FOOD, SHELTER, EDUCATION AND
INVESTING FOR RETIREMENT.
LET'S SAY FOR ARGUMENT SAKE THAT
IS $250,000 A YEAR, WHICH MIGHT
BE GENEROUS.
ABOVE AND BEYOND THAT LEVEL OF
INCOME, YOU'RE LIKELY SAVING,
INVESTING OR SPENDING ON LIFE'S
EXTRAS, NOT THE NECESSITIES.
MIGHT BE PRIVATE SCHOOLING OR
TRAVEL OR LEISURE OR
ENTREPRENEURIAL PURSUITS.
WHILE THE RICH MAY NOT WANT THE
TAXES ON EVERY DOLLAR ABOVE
$400,000 RAISED BY 4.6
PERCENTAGE POINTS THERE IS NO
STRONG ARGUMENT IT WILL SLOW
DOWN HOW FOLKS EARNING THAT MUCH
MONEY HERE IN THE U.S. SPEND
THEIR MONEY IN A WAY THAT
BENEFITS THE ECONOMY.
DOESN'T MEAN WE SHOULD INCREASE
THEIR TAXES.
I'M JUST SAYING DON'T PUT TOO
MUCH CREDENCE IN THE ARGUMENT
THAT IT WILL HURT THE ECONOMY.
ON THE MONEY MENU TODAY,
AMERICANS ARE PAYING LESS AT THE
PUMP.
THE AVERAGE PRICE FOR A GALLON
OF UNLEADED REGULAR GASOLINE IS
$2.24.
CHEAPER OIL FROM THE UNITED
STATES AND CANADA IS COMING
ONLINE.
TOYOTA IS IN TROUBLE AGAIN WITH
U.S. AUTHORITIES AFTER FAILING
TO REPORT A SAFETY DEFECT IN THE
2010 LEXUS 350.
THE JAPANESE AUTOMAKER AGREED TO
PAY A RECORD $17.4 MILLION FINE
FOR NOT COMING CLEAN ON THE
DEFECT WITH A FLOOR MAT.
NOW, IT IS THE LARGEST FINE
ALO
ALLOWED FOR SINGLE
INVESTIGATION.
THE MAT ALLEGEDLY TRAPPED THE
GAS PEDAL DOWN, CAUSING UNWANTED
ACCELERATION.
TOYOTA FINALLY INITIATED A
RECALL IN JUNE.
THAT WASN'T SOON ENOUGH FOR
AUTHORITIES.
NEXT MONTH, INSTAGRAM WILL START
SELLING PHOTOS THAT MEMBERS POST
ON THE SITE FOR USE IN ADS.
THE PHOTO SHARING SITE SAYS IT
IS CHANGING ITS TERMS OF SERVICE
ON JANUARY 17th, ALLOWING IT TO
GIVE CONTENT TO THIRD PARTIES.
FOR EXAMPLE, INSTAGRAM COULD LET
A MAJOR RETAIL CHAIN BUY PHOTOS
OF PEOPLE SHOPPING IN THEIR
STORES, TO RUN IN AN AD.
THE MOVE COMES MONTHS AFTER
FACEBOOK TOOK OVER INSTAGRAM.
IT IS OFTEN QUESTIONED ON
PRIVACY ISSUES.
THE FALLOUT FROM THE MASS
SHOOTING AT A CONNECTICUT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL TARGETS THE
GUN INDUSTRY.
PRESSURE IS MOUNTING IN
WASHINGTON TO TIGHTEN FEDERAL
GUN LAWS JUST DAYS AFTER THE
TRAGEDY.
BUT GUN MANUFACTURERS ARE ALSO
STARTING TO SEE THE COMMERCIAL
FALLOUT FROM THE NEWTOWN
SHOOTING.
DICK'S SPORTING GOODS, A CHAIN
WITH STORES ACROSS THE COUNTRY,
ANNOUNCED IT IS SUSPENDING SALES
OF ALL SO-CALLED MODERN SPORTING
RIFLES FROM ITS STORES AND
REMOVING THEM, QUOTE, OUT OF
RESPECT FOR THE VICTIMS AND
THEIR FAMILIES.
THAT REFERS TO SEMI-AUTOMATIC
RIFLES LIKE THE BUSHMASTER USED
BY THE GUNMAN IN THE ATTACK.
WALMART REMOVED A SEMI-AUTOMATIC
RIFLE MADE BY THE SAME MAKER AS
THAT OF THE BUSHMASTER FROM ITS
WEBSITE, THOUGH IT CONTINUES TO
SELL THE FIREARM IN STORE.
INVESTMENT FIRM CERBERUS, WHICH
OWNS BUSHMASTER'S MAKER, FREEDOM
GROUP, SAID TODAY THAT IT WANTS
TO GET OUT OF THE GUN BUSINESS.
MEANWHILE, SHARES OF
SMITH & WESSON, ONE OF THE
BIGGEST PUBLICLY TRADED
GUNMAKERS TUMBLED 20% OVER THE
LAST THREE DAYS.
CABELLIA'S HAS FALLEN 12%.
GUNMAKER STURM RUGER IS ABOUT
15% LOWER.
OVER THE LAST FEW YEARS,
VIRTUALLY NOTHING HAS HURT THE
GUN INDUSTRY IN THIS COUNTRY,
INCLUDING NUMEROUS MASS SHOOTING
INCIDENTS.
THIS ONE, THOUGH, MAY BE
DIFFERENT.
AND IT IS SOMETHING WE'LL ALL BE
WATCHING.
FROM NEW YORK, I'M ALI VELSHI.
SAME TIME TOMORROW.
HING,
ISN'T A THING AT ALL?
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
♪
BECOMING
PART OF THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
TREES WILL TALK TO NETWORKS
WILL TALK TO SCIENTISTS
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE.
CARS WILL TALK TO ROAD SENSORS
WILL TALK TO STOPLIGHTS
ABOUT TRAFFIC EFFICIENCY.
THE AMBULANCE WILL TALK
TO PATIENT RECORDS
WILL TALK TO DOCTORS
ABOUT SAVING LIVES.
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
THE NEXT BIG THING?
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
♪
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
♪
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
I'M GOING TO DREAM
ABOUT THAT STEAK.
ABOUT THAT TIRAMISU.
WHAT A NIGHT, HUH?
BUT, UM, CAN THE TEST DRIVE
BE OVER NOW?
HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A PASSAT.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN, $0 DUE AT SIGNING,
$0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
ELEMENTARY HAS ALSO AFFECTED
MOVIE RELEASES.
DJANGO UNCHAINED WAS SUPPOSED TO
BE RELEASED TODAY.
HOWEVER ITS DISTRIBUTOR RELEASED
THIS STATEMENT, QUOTE, IN THIS
TIME OF NATIONAL MOURNING WE
HAVE DECIDED TO FOREGO OUR
NATIONAL EVENT.
PRIVATE SCREENING FOR THE CAST
AND CREW CONTAINS BLOODY SCENES
OF SHOOTINGS.
THE DIRECTOR AND HIS STARS
ADDRESSED FRIDAY'S SHOOTING AND
MOVIE CONTAINING EXTREME
VIOLENCE.
>> IT'S JUST A HORRIBLE TRAGEDY.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO SAY ABOUT
IT?
I MEAN, IT'S HORRIBLE.
BUT AT THE SAME TIME, NO, I
DON'T THINK IT HAS ANYTHING TO
DO WITH THEM.
BUT THIS HAS GONE ALL THE WAY
BACK DOWN TO SHAKESPEARE'S DAYS.
>> WHAT I CONSIDER THE REALLY
SIGNIFICANT AND DANGEROUS ASPECT
IS THE SENSE OF -- THE
SENSATIONISM OF IT AND MOVIES
DON'T SENSATIONALIZE.
THEY JUST TELL IT IT.
WHO SENSATIONALIZES IT?
THE MEDIA?
SO WE HAVE TO LOOK AT THEM
SEPARATELY AND NOT MUDDLE IT ALL
UP AND POINT FINGERS AT THE OPT
SIT SIDE.
I FIND THAT VERY IMPORTANT.
>> THERE IS ANOTHER FILM
FEATURED HERE.
IT'S CALLED "JACK REACHER."
ITS FILMING IS POSTPONED
JUST $1.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
.
>>> HERE IS JUST A LITTLE
SOMETHING THAT WE HOPE WILL PUT
A SMILE ON YOUR FACE.
POURING INTO THE SMALL NEW
ENGLAND TOWN, I SPOKE WITH
FIREFIGHTERS LAST NIGHT WHO TOLD
ME JUST THE OUTPOURING OF
SUPPORT COMING FROM FIRE
DEPARTMENTS AND CHURCHES AND
PEOPLE ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
IT'S STUNNING.
ARE THERE NOTES ATTACHED TO THE
TEDDY BEAR.
>> THERE'S SO MANY COMING.
>> GARBAGE BAGS AND GARBAGE BAGS
OF TEDDY BEARS AS GIFTS TO THE
CHILDREN IN THE COMMUNITY?
>> YEP.
>> AND SO WHAT HAVE YOU DONE
WITH THEM SO FAR?
>> WE'VE BEEN TRYING TO
DISTRIBUTE THEM TO LOCAL CHURCH
GROUPS.
WE WERE DOWN AT THE NEWTOWN
YOUTH ACADEMY.
THEY HAD A BUMP OF THE KIDS
THERE AND DISTRIBUTED THEM
THERE.
>> AND THOSE TWO VOLUNTEER
FIREFIGHTERS I SPOKE TO SAID THE
LETTERS AND CARDS AND TEDDY
BEARS THAT THEY ARE ALL GETTING
IN THE DISTRIBUTION, THAT'S
ACTUALLY HELPING THEM HEAL AS
WELL.
HEALING, DON LEMON.
HEALING.
NOT MOVING ON BUT MOVING
FORWARD.
THAT IS WHAT NEWTOWN IS NOW
DOING.
>> Reporter: YEAH.
AND LISTEN, IT'S GOING TO TAKE
SOME TIME.
WE CAN ONLY JUST IMAGINE.
I CAN'T REALLY IMAGINE WHAT IS
GOING ON BUT I CAN SHOW YOU
HERE, THE OUTPOURING HERE.
THINGS HAVE JUST BEEN STACKED ON
TOP OF THINGS.
THERE HAVE BEEN TEDDY BEARS AND
FLOWERS.
THEY HAVE ERECTED A TENT, PUT UP
AN ANGEL AND A WREATH.
YOU CAN SEE PEOPLE LIGHTING
CANDLES.
A ROCKING HORSE THAT SOMEONE HAS
PUT HERE AND PUT TO ALL OF THE
CLASSMATES.
EMILY, WITH LOVE FROM ALL OF OUR
CLASSMATES AND A CROSS WHERE
PEOPLE ARE CONTINUING TO COME
OUT TO SHOW THEIR SUPPORT AND
LOVE.
AS YOU SAID, BROOKE, HEALING.
HEALING.
IT'S GOING TO TAKE A WHILE BUT
WE PRAY THAT THESE FOLKS WILL
HEAL IN TIME.
>> DON LEMON, THANK YOU FOR YOUR
COVERAGE THERE.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH ME.
I'M BROOKE BALDWIN.
WE'LL TAKE YOU BACK TO NEWTOWN
WITH WOLF BLITZE "THE SITUATION
ROOM" STARTS RIGHT AFTER THIS.
VR
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
but with ADVAIR,
I'm breathing better.
So now I can be in
the scene.
ADVAIR is
clinically proven to help
significantly improve
lung function.
Unlike most COPD medications,
ADVAIR contains both an
anti-inflammatory
and a
long-acting bronchodilator
working together to help improve
your lung function all day.
ADVAIR won't
replace fast-acting inhalers
for sudden symptoms
and should not be used more
than twice a day.
People with
COPD taking ADVAIR
may have a higher chance
of pneumonia.
ADVAIR may increase your
risk of osteoporosis
and some eye problems.
Tell your doctor
if you have a heart condition
or high blood pressure before
taking ADVAIR.
If you're still
having difficulty breathing,
ask your doctor if including
ADVAIR could help
improve your lung function.
Get your
first full
prescription
free
and save
on refills
at
ADVAIRcopd.com.