>> YEAH, SOLEMN DAY TODAY ACROSS
AMERICA AND, OF COURSE, IN THE
SO CNN NEWSROOM.
ONE OF THE SIX ADULTS VICTIM OF
THE SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, PARENT TOLD US THEY
WERE IN A MEETING YESTERDAY WITH
THE PRINCIPAL AND VICE PRINCIPAL
ALONG WITH MARY SHERLOCK WHEN
THEY HEARD THE LOUD POP, POP,
POP, THEY WENT TO CHECK THAT OUT
IN THE HALLWAY.
SHERLOCK AND THE PRINCIPAL
DIDN'T RETURN ALIVE.
JUST A VERY SOLEMN OUTCOME TO
THAT.
SHERLOCK WAS PART OF A TEAM THAT
WAS REALLY RELIED UPON THERE AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
SHE WAS PART OF THE SCHOOL'S
CRISIS INTERVENTION TEAM, ALI.
SO EVEN IN A TIME LIKE THIS WHEN
PEOPLE ARE TURNING TO THOSE FOR
COMFORT, SHE'S NO LONGER WITH
US.
ALI?
>> YEAH, SAD STORY.
NICK VALENCIA AT THE CNN CENTER
IN ATLANTA.
THANKS, NICK.
>>> GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE.
I'M ALI VELSHI.
YOU'RE WATCHING OUR SPECIAL
COVERAGE OF THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
I'M IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
ABOUT A BLOCK AWAY FROM THE
SCHOOL WHICH IS ROUGHLY BEHIND
ME.
A BLOCK AWAY FROM THE SCENE OF
THE HORRIBLE MASSACRE.
HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW RIGHT NOW.
IN ABOUT AN HOUR, OFFICIALS ARE
EXPECTED TO START RELEASING THE
NAMES OF THE VICTIMS.
WE'VE LEARNED THE NAMES OF TWO
OF THE ADULTS, THE PRINCIPAL AND
A SCHOOL COUNSELOR, BUT NOT THE
NAMES OF THE CHILDREN.
NOW, THAT IS EXPECTED TO START
HAPPENING AT AROUND 8:00 A.M.
RIGHT WHERE I AM.
RIGHT NOW THE BODIES ARE STILL
INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
POLICE SAY IT'S AN ACTIVE CRIME
SCENE AND THAT MEANS THE
SHOOTER'S BODY IS STILL THERE,
AS WELL.
POLICE SAY 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM
LANZA WAS THE SHOOTER, AND ALSO
SAY HIS MOTHER'S BODY WAS FOUND
INSIDE THE HOME THEY SHARED
TOGETHER ABOUT 2 1/2 MILES FROM
HERE.
>> I'M JOHN BERMAN IN THE TOWN
SQUARE HERE IN NEWTOWN.
FLAGS FLYING AT HALF STAFF HERE
ALL AROUND THE COUNTRY TO HONOR
THOSE LOST AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL SHOOTING HERE IN NEWTOWN,
THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
PRESIDENT OBAMA OFFERED HIS OWN
THOUGHTS THIS MORNING IN HIS
WEEKLY ADDRESS.
THOUGHTS ON THE TRAGEDY, AND
THOUGHTS ON GUNS.
>> ON FRIDAY, WE LEARNED THAT
MORE THAN TWO DOZEN PEOPLE WERE
KILLED WHEN A GUNMAN OPENED FIRE
IN AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
MOST OF THOSE WHO DIED WERE JUST
YOUNG CHILDREN WITH THEIR WHOLE
LIVES AHEAD OF THEM.
AND EVERY PARENT IN AMERICA HAS
A HEART HEAVY WITH HURT.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS, MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES TO HELPING
OUR CHILDREN FULFILL THEIR
DREAMS.
SO OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN TODAY.
WE GRIEVE FOR THE FAMILIES OF
THOSE WE LOST.
AND WE KEEP IN OUR PRAYERS THE
PARENTS OF THOSE WHO SURVIVED.
BECAUSE AS BLESSED AS THEY ARE
TO HAVE THEIR CHILDREN HOME,
THEY KNOW THAT THEIR CHILD'S
INNOCENCE HAS BEEN TORN AWAY FAR
TOO EARLY.
AS A NATION, WE HAVE ENDURED FAR
TOO MANY OF THESE TRAGEDIES IN
THE LAST FEW YEARS.
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
A SHOPPING MALL IN OREGON, A
HOUSE OF WORSHIP IN WISCONSIN, A
MOVIE THEATER IN COLORADO,
COUNTLESS STREET CORNERS IN
PLACES LIKE CHICAGO AND
PHILADELPHIA.
ANY OF THESE NEIGHBORHOODS COULD
BE OUR OWN.
SO WE HAVE TO COME TOGETHER, AND
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO TAKE
MEANINGFUL ACTION TO PREVENT
MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS FROM
HAPPENING.
REGARDLESS OF POLITICS.
THIS WEEKEND, MICHELLE AND I ARE
DOING WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT
IS DOING, HOLDING OUR CHILDREN
AS CLOSE AS WE CAN AND REMINDING
THEM HOW MUCH WE LOVE THEM.
THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CAN'T DO THAT
TODAY.
AND THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT
NOW.
BECAUSE WHILE NOTHING CAN TAKE
THE PLACE OF A LOST CHILD OR
LOVED ONE, ALL OF US CAN EXTEND
A HAND TO THOSE OF US IN NEED.
TO REMIND THEM WE'RE THERE FOR
THEM, THAT WE'RE PRAYING FOR
THEM.
AND THAT THE LOVE THEY FELT FOR
THOSE THEY LOST ENDURES NOT JUST
IN THEIR OWN MEMORIES BUT ALSO
IN THEIR COMMUNITIES AND IN
THEIR COUNTRY.
THANK YOU AND GOD BLESS YOU.
>> WE ARE LEARNING CHILLING
DETAILS OF WHAT HAPPENED WHEN
THE GUNMAN BURST INTO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
SOME OF THOSE DETAILS ARE COMING
FROM YOUNG SURVIVORS.
CHILDREN WHO WERE IN THAT SCHOOL
DURING THE RAMPAGE AND WHO WERE
ABLE TO ESCAPE.
HERE'S CNN'S BRIAN TODD.
>> Reporter: THE ACCOUNT OF A
YOUNG BOY SAID TO BE DELIVERING
AN ATTENDANCE REPORT TO THE
OFFICE AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL WHEN THE SHOOTINGS TOOK
PLACE IS SURREAL.
>> I SAW SOME OF THE BULLETS
GOING PAST THE HALL THAT I WAS
RIGHT NEXT TO.
AND THEN A TEACHER PULLED ME
INTO HER CLASSROOM.
>> HE SAID HE HEARD A SOUND LIKE
SOMEONE KICKING A DOOR.
HIS MOTHER CLINGING TO HIM HAD
WORDS OF THANKS.
>> I'M SO GRATEFUL TO THE
TEACHER WHO SAVED HIM.
>> YOU THINK THE TEACHER SAVED
HIS LIFE?
>> SHE DEFINITELY DID.
HE HAD BULLETS GOING BY HIM AND
SHE GRABBED HIM AND ANOTHER
CHILD AND PULLED HIM INTO A
CLASSROOM.
>> BRENDAN MURRAY, A FOURTH
GRADER DESCRIBED THE CHAOS.
>> I WAS IN THE GYM AT THE TIME
AND SO, THE TEACHERS, WE HEARD
LOTS OF BANGS AND WE THOUGHT
THAT IT WAS THE CUSTODIAN
KNOCKING STUFF DOWN.
WE HEARD SCREAMING.
AND SO, WE -- WE WENT TO THE
WALL AND WE SAT DOWN.
AND THEN POLICE CAME IN.
AND IT WAS LIKE, IS HE IN HERE
AND RAN OUT.
AND WHEN SOMEBODY YELLED GET TO
A SAFE PLACE.
SO WE WENT TO THE CLOSET IN THE
GYM AND SAT THERE FOR A LITTLE
WHILE.
AND THEN THE POLICE WERE
KNOCKING ON THE DOOR AND WERE
LIKE, WE'RE EVACUATING PEOPLE.
WE'RE EVACUATING PEOPLE.
>> CNN IS ONLY AIRING SOUND OF
CHILDREN WHOSE PARENTS GAVE
PERMISSION.
AS ONE WOMAN WALKED AWAY FROM
THE SCHOOL SHE WAS HEARD CRYING
WHY, WHY.
A POLICEMAN WAS HEARD SAYING IT
WAS THE WORST THING HE'D SEEN IN
HIS CAREER.
A NURSE FROM NEARBY DANBURY
HOSPITAL DESCRIBED THE SCENE
THERE AS PARENTS WAITED FOR WORD
ABOUT THEIR CHILDREN.
>> PARENTS, ALL THESE PARENTS
WERE WAITING FOR THEIR CHILDREN
TO COME OUT.
THEY THOUGHT THEY WERE, YOU
KNOW, STILL ALIVE.
AND THERE'S 20 PARENTS THAT WERE
JUST TOLD THAT THEIR CHILDREN
ARE DEAD.
IT WAS AWFUL.
>> THE FATHER OF A YOUNG GIRL
WHO SURVIVED WAS JUST TRYING TO
PROCESS IT ALL.
>> IT WAS SHOCKING.
I GOT THE CALL AT WORK THIS
MORNING AND -- I CAN'T BELIEVE A
SMALL TOWN LIKE THIS WOULD EVER
HAVE ANYTHING LIKE THIS HAPPEN.
AND TO BE IN AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, IT'S UNHEARD OF.
>> BY LATE FRIDAY AFTERNOON AND
INTO THE EVENING, EVACUATED
CHILDREN WERE BEING CARED FOR
AND REUNITING WITH THEIR PARENTS
AT A NEARBY FIRE HOUSE.
BRIAN TODD, CNN, WASHINGTON.
>> WE'RE ALSO GETTING A LOT OF
QUESTIONS ABOUT HOW YOU CAN HELP
THOSE AFFECTED.
IF YOU WANT TO HELP, GO TO
CNN.COM/IMPACT.
JOHN?
>> THANKS SO MUCH, ALI.
AS EVERYONE KNOWS, OUR FOCUS AS
MUCH AS IT CAN BE IS ON VICTIMS.
THERE IS AN INVESTIGATION GOING
ON RIGHT NOW.
THERE ARE SO MANY QUESTIONS.
AND WE'RE LEARNING MORE NOW
ABOUT THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER IN
THIS CASE.
POLICE SAY HIS NAME IS ADAM
LANZA.
CNN'S MARY SNOW IS AT LANZA'S
HOME.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT THE
SUSPECTED SHOOTER?
>> Reporter: JOHN, IT'S BELIEVED
THAT HE LIVED WITH HIS MOTHER AT
THE HOME THAT IS BEHIND ME NOW
BLOCKED OFF BY POLICE.
AND IN TERMS OF DESCRIPTIONS OF
HIM, ONE NEIGHBOR DESCRIBED HIM
AS TROUBLED.
FORMER CLASSMATES DESCRIBED HIM
AS VERY BRIGHT, SOMEONE WHO KEPT
TO HIMSELF SOCIALLY AWKWARD, AND
WE'RE ALSO LEARNING FROM OUR --
CNN'S SUSAN CANDIOTTI THAT A LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIAL TOLD HER
THAT A FAMILY MEMBER OF LANZA
TOLD INVESTIGATORS THAT HE HAD A
FORM OF AUTISM.
>> MARY, WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT
THE GUNS?
THE WEAPONS THAT HE USED IN THE
SHOOTING?
WE UNDERSTAND THERE WERE TWO
PISTOLS, ALSO A RIFLE PERHAPS
FOUND IN THE CAR.
>> Reporter: AND LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS SO FAR ARE SAYING WHAT
CNN HAS LEARNED IS THEY WERE
LEGALLY PURCHASED BY HIS MOTHER
NANCY LANZA.
>> ALL RIGHT.
MARY SNOW, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
WE'LL BE CHECKING IN WITH YOU
ALL MORNING.
ALI?
>> YOU WERE TALKING ABOUT THE
GUNS, JOHN, LET'S FOCUS IN ON
THE WEAPONS USED ON THE ATTACK.
OUR NATIONAL CORRESPONDENT SUSAN
CANDIOTTI HAS THAT PART OF OUR
COVERAGE.
SUSAN?
>> WE'RE TRYING TO GET DOWN TO
THE BOTTOM A BIT MORE ABOUT THIS
MAN, THIS SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA,
20 YEARS OLD, WE KNOW ACCORDING
TO OUR SOURCES THAT WHEN HE CAME
TO THAT SCHOOL HE WAS ARMED WITH
THREE GUNS.
HE WAS WEARING WHAT IS DESCRIBED
TO ME AS BLACK BATTLE FATIGUES
AND A MILITARY VEST.
NOW, WHERE DID HE GET THESE
THREE GUNS?
AND WHAT KIND WERE THEY?
THE THREE GUNS WERE TWO
HANDGUNS, A GLOCK, AND A SIG
SAUER AS WELL AS A .223 BUSH
MASTER.
THIS IS A SEMIAUTOMATIC GUN.
WE'VE GOT PHOTOGRAPHS OF THE
TYPE OF WEAPON IT IS.
WE UNDERSTAND FROM OUR SOURCES
THAT THESE GUNS WERE ALL
REGISTERED BELONGED TO HIS
MOTHER, HIS MOTHER WHO WAS ALSO
KILLED.
NOW, THE MOTHER'S BODY WAS FOUND
IN THE HOUSE WHERE A FAMILY HOME
HERE IN THIS AREA.
WE DON'T KNOW MUCH MORE ABOUT --
ABOUT ADAM LANZA.
WE DO KNOW THAT HIS BROTHER RYAN
WHO WAS A BIT OLDER, 24 YEARS
OLD, HE WAS TAKEN IN TO CUSTODY
FOR QUESTIONING.
HE IS NOT BEING CALLED A
SUSPECT, BUT HE WAS IN HOBOKEN,
NEW JERSEY, WHEN THEY BROUGHT
HIM IN FOR QUESTIONING.
THAT'S WHERE HE LIVES TO TRY TO
FIND OUT WHAT IF ANYTHING HE
KNEW ABOUT THIS.
WHAT HE COULD TELL THEM ABOUT
HIS BROTHER.
WHAT INFORMATION THEY -- HE CAN
GIVE ABOUT HIS BACKGROUND.
AND POLICE ALSO QUESTIONED THEIR
FATHER.
HE STILL LIVES IN THIS AREA.
HE IS DIVORCED FROM HIS WIFE WHO
WAS ONE OF THE VICTIMS HERE, AND
HE HAS REMARRIED.
SO HE TOO IS BEING QUESTIONED BY
POLICE TO TRY TO SHED SOME LIGHT
ON ADAM LANZA AND WHY THIS
TRAGEDY HAPPENED.
>> THANKS FOR THAT.
A LOT OF QUESTIONS ARE FORMING
AROUND THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER
NANCY LANZA, THE REGISTERED
OWNER OF THE THREE WEAPONS AS
SUSAN TOLD US.
GUNS SIMILAR TO THESE AS WE'RE
SHOWING YOU NOW, A GLOCK
REVOLVER, A GLOCK PISTOL, A SIG
SAUER AND A RIFLE.
I'M JOINED BY A CNN CONTRIBUTOR.
THERE ARE A LOT OF QUESTIONS
ABOUT THE ASSAULT RIFLE FIRST.
THIS WAS LEGALLY PURCHASED BY
NANCY LANZA, WHY WOULD SHE NEED
A SEMIAUTOMATIC?
AND WHAT THE LAWS ARE AROUND
ACQUIRING ONE?
>> WELL, THE LAWS ARE THAT YOU
COULD ACQUIRE IT.
THERE HAD BEEN A BAN IN PLACE
THAT MICHIGAN DURING THE CLINTON
ADMINISTRATION.
BUT IT WAS ALLOWED TO EXPIRE AND
IT'S NOT BEEN RENEWED.
ANYONE THAT CAN BUY A PISTOL CAN
BUY ONE OF THESE WEAPONS.
THAT BUSH MASTER .223, THAT'S
THE SAME CALIBER OUR MILITARY
CARRIED IN VIETNAM AND SINCE
IT'S USED IN THE M-16 AND M-4
AUTOMATIC RIFLES.
IN THIS CASE, YOU WOULD HAVE TO
KEEP PULLING THE TRIGGER, BUT
YOU CAN FIRE AS MANY BULLETS AS
QUICKLY AS YOU CAN PULL THE
TRIGGER WITH THAT GUN AND THE
TWO HANDGUNS.
>> AND FOR THE BENEFIT OF OUR
VIEWERS, WHO ARE NOT FAMILIAR
WITH GUNS.
THE TERM SEMIAUTOMATIC MEANS YOU
KEEP PULLING THE TRIGGER, YOU
DON'T HOLD IT DOWN ONCE, BUT YOU
DON'T HAVE TO DO SOMETHING TO
SHOOT AGAIN.
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
AND IN THE CASE OF A
SEMIAUTOMATIC PISTOL, THE
BULLETS ARE FED IN THROUGH A
MAGAZINE AND THEY CAN RANGE IN
SIZE FROM SEVEN OR EIGHT ROUNDS
TO 15 ROUNDS.
THE TWO GUNS YOU'VE BEEN SHOWING
PICTURES OF WOULD APPEAR TO BE
THE 15-ROUND STANDARD SIZED
MAGAZINES FOR THOSE GUNS.
BUT YOU CAN BUY EXTENDED
MAGAZINES AS WAS SEEN IN OTHER
SHOOTINGS IN THE PAST THAT CAN
GO 30 ROUNDS OR EVEN MORE.
AND, AGAIN, IT'S AS QUICKLY AS
YOU CAN PULL THE TRIGGER.
AS OPPOSED TO THE REVOLVER WHICH
IS ONLY GOING TO HOLD SIX ROUNDS
AND YOU HAVE TO STOP AND REFEED
MANUALLY EACH OF THE BULLETS
INTO THE CHAMBER, CLOSE IT UP
AND BEGIN SHOOTING AGAIN.
WITH A SEMIAUTOMATIC, YOU FIRE
AS FAST AS YOU CAN GO, DROP THAT
MAGAZINE, PUT A NEW ONE IN AND
KEEP ON GOING.
AND, AGAIN, IF HE HAD TO STOP
AND RELOAD SEVERAL TIMES, HE'S
PROBABLY NOT GOING TO BE JUMPED
ON BY 5-YEAR-OLDS WHILE HE'S IN
THE RE-LOADING PROCESS.
AND, OF COURSE, THE TEACHERS ARE
IN THE PROCESS OF TRYING TO SAVE
THE CHILDREN AND HUDDLE THEM.
SO HE'S GOING TO HAVE NO
OPPOSITION PHYSICALLY BY ANY OF
THE VICTIMS WHILE HE'S SHOOTING,
WHILE HE'S RELOADING AND THEN
RESHOOTING.
>> TOM, THERE ARE MANY REASONS
WHY AN OWNER WOULD CHOOSE A
PISTOL OVER A REVOLVER, BUT ONE
OF THE ADVANTAGES OF THE PISTOL,
ONE OF THE ADVANTAGES OF THAT IS
IN ORDER TO RELOAD, YOU CAN
RELOAD AS YOU SAID IN THESE
CASES POSSIBLY 15 ROUNDS VERY
INSTANTLY.
YOU PRESS A BUTTON, THE MAGAZINE
DROPS OUT AND YOU PUT ANOTHER
LOADED MAGAZINE IN.
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
YOU CAN SHOOT A MUCH MORE RAPID
PACE OF FIRE WITH A
SEMIAUTOMATIC PISTOL THAN YOU
CAN A REVOLVER.
AND ESPECIALLY THE QUALITY
PISTOLS LIKE A GLOCK OR SIG
SAUER HAVE BECOME THE CHOICE OF
LAW ENFORCEMENT BECAUSE OF THAT
REASON.
THEY'RE HIGH QUALITY AND ALLOW A
RAPID RATE OF FIRE WHILE IN USE.
>> DOES IT STRIKE YOU AS UNUSUAL
THAT SOMEBODY WOULD BE OWNING
THESE THREE WEAPONS?
OR IS THIS NORMAL FOR SOMEBODY
WHO WOULD OWN GUNS?
>> I WOULDN'T CALL IT NORMAL,
BUT, YOU KNOW, IT'S ESTIMATED
THERE'S 285 MILLION GUNS AT
LARGE IN THIS COUNTRY WITH A
POPULATION OF A LITTLE OVER 300
MILLION.
SO THERE'S A LOT OF GUNS,
HANDGUNS, ASSAULT RIFLES, A
VARIETY OF WEAPONS THAT ARE OUT
THERE, AND ARE PERFECTLY LEGAL
TO ACQUIRE AS WE'VE SEEN.
AND IN THIS CASE, IF THE MOTHER
ACQUIRED THE WEAPONS, AND
ACQUIRED THEM LEGALLY, THEN YOU
DON'T HAVE THE SITUATION OF
MENTALLY DISTURBED CHILD GOING
THROUGH THE TESTING OR GOING
THROUGH ANY KIND OF BACKGROUND
CHECK TO GET THE WEAPON.
HE JUST TAKES HER WEAPONS AND
USES THEM AGAINST HER AND THE
OTHER VICTIMS IN THIS CASE.
>> AND CONNECTICUT DOES HAVE
SOME OF THE STRICTER GUN LAWS IN
THIS COUNTRY.
THANKS, WE'LL CHECK IN WITH YOU
THROUGH THE COURSE OF THE
MORNING.
26 LIVES CUT SHORT AFTER DOING
SOMETHING SO ROUTINE, GOING TO
WORK AND GOING TO SCHOOL.
WE ARE TRYING TO FIND OUT MORE
INFORMATION ABOUT THE VICTIMS.
YOU'RE WATCHING OUR COVERAGE
LIVE FROM CONNECTICUT.
I PUT AWAY MONEY.
I WAS 21, SO I SAID,
"HMM, I WANT TO RETIRE AT 55."
AND BEFORE YOU KNOW IT,
I'M 58 YEARS OLD.
TIME WENT BY VERY FAST.
IT GOES BY TOO, TOO FAST.
♪
BUT I WOULD DO IT AGAIN
IN A HEARTBEAT.
[ laughs ]
♪
EVERYTHING ABOUT
THE ORAL-B POWER BRUSH
IS SIMPLY REVOLUTIONARY.
OUR UNIQUE BRUSH HEAD CLEANS
IN THREE DIRECTIONS
WITH UP TO 50% MORE
BRUSH MOVEMENTS
THAN LEADING
SONIC TECHNOLOGY.
ORAL-B POWER BRUSHES.
GO TO ORALB.COM
FOR THE LATEST OFFERS.
YOU WANNA SEE IF WALMART HAS
SIMILAR GIFTS FOR LESS?
YEAH.
LET'S GO.
SAMSUNG GALAXY S3 --
OVER FIFTY DOLLARS LESS
THAN BEST BUY!
WOW! FIFTY BUCKS!
YEAH!
THAT'S A PAIR OF SHOES.
SEE FOR YOURSELF IF YOU COULD
SAVE ON THE GIFTS YOU WANT.
WALMART.
>>> I WANT TO WELCOME YOU BACK
TO A SOMBER MORNING.
A SPECIAL COVERAGE OF THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTING.
I'M ALI VELSHI HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, NEAR THE SCENE OF
THE ATTACK ON AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
IT'S JUST BEHIND ME OVER THAT
RIDGE WHICH LEFT 20 CHILDREN
DEAD AND SIX ADULTS.
IN LESS THAN AN HOUR AROUND 8:00
EASTERN THIS MORNING, WE ARE
EXPECTING POLICE RIGHT HERE TO
RELEASE THE NAMES OF THE VICTIMS
KILLED INSIDE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
LET'S CHECK IN NOW WITH NICK
VALENCIA IN THE CNN CENTER IN
ATLANTA.
NICK, WE KNOW THE SCHOOL
PRINCIPAL WAS ONE OF THE ADULTS
KILLED ALONG WITH THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST.
I'M HEARING YOU JUST GOT OFF THE
PHONE WITH ANOTHER TEACHER WHO
WAS THERE WHEN IT HAPPENED.
TELL US WHAT SHE SAID.
>> GOOD MORNING, ALI, I JUST
SPOKE TO A TEACHER, ONE OF THE
MUSIC TEACHERS WHO IS BEING
CALLED A HERO AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
IT'S REPORTED THAT SHE
BARRICADED HERSELF ALONG WITH A
GROUP OF CHILDREN WHILE THE
SUSPECTED GUNMAN KNOCKED ON THE
DOOR TRYING TO GET IN.
I SPOKE TO HER EARLIER THIS
MORNING FROM HER HOME IN
SEYMOUR, CONNECTICUT, SHE TOLD
US, ALI, IT'S A LITTLE BIT TOO
HARD TO TALK RIGHT NOW.
BUT HER PRAYERS AND THOUGHTS ARE
WITH HER FRIENDS AND FAMILIES OF
THOSE THAT LOST LOVED ONES.
ALI?
>> OH, WOW.
WHAT ELSE HAVE YOU GOT ON
VICTIMS, NICK?
>> WELL, AS YOU MENTIONED, ALI,
26 PEOPLE DIED IN ALL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, YESTERDAY.
SIX OF THOSE ADULTS, ONE OF THEM
IS 56-YEAR-OLD MARY SHERLOCK, A
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST, AND THERE'S
NO DOUBTING HER SUCCESS, ALI,
SHE'D BEEN THROUGH THREE SCHOOL
SYSTEMS BEFORE LANDING AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WHERE SHE
WAS A FIXTURE THERE IN THE
EDUCATION DEPARTMENT.
A LOT OF PEOPLE REMEMBER HER AS
BEING THE PERSON THEY WOULD GO
TO DURING CRISIS SITUATIONS.
SO, YOU KNOW, SHE'S NOT AROUND
NOW.
THE PERSON THAT PEOPLE WOULD
TURN TO IN A SITUATION LIKE
THIS.
WE'RE HEARING SHE WAS IN A
MEETING YESTERDAY WITH THE
PRINCIPAL AND VICE PRINCIPAL
ALONG WITH ANOTHER PARENT WHO
SPOKE TO CNN YESTERDAY ON
FRIDAY, THEY TOLD US THEY HEARD
THE LOUD POP, POP, POPS COMING
FROM THE GUN IN THE HALLWAY.
THEY WENT TO INVESTIGATE AND
TRIED TO FIGURE OUT WHAT THE
NOISE WAS, SHERLOCK AND THE
PRINCIPAL PERISHED, THEY DIDN'T
COME BACK ALIVE.
ALI, WE KNOW THAT MARY SHERLOCK,
56 YEARS OLD WAS AN EXPERT IN
PSYCHOLOGY WITH A MASTERS FROM
SOUTHERN CONNECTICUT STATE
UNIVERSITY.
SHE ALSO WORKED IN THE COMMUNITY
AT A GROUP HOME FOR DISABLED
ADULTS.
AND AS I MENTIONED, SHE WAS PART
OF THAT SCHOOL'S CRISIS
INTERVENTION TEAM.
SHERLOCK WAS ALSO A FAMILY WOMAN
MARRIED FOR 31 YEARS, ALI, SHE
LEAVES BEHIND HER HUSBAND BILL
ALONG WITH TWO DAUGHTERS, BOTH
IN THEIR 20s.
SHE LISTS AMONG HER ACTIVITIES
THAT SHE LIKED HER HOBBIES, SHE
LIKED TO GARDEN, SPEND TIME AT
THE LAKE AND GO TO THE THEATER.
SHE WON'T BE ABLE TO DO ANY OF
THAT ANYMORE.
ALI?
>> 26 PEOPLE KILLED, MANY MORE
SHATTERED FAMILIES, HUNDREDS IN
THIS COMMUNITY ARE REELING THIS
MORNING AS THEY WAKE UP.
AND THEY'RE GOING TO LEARN MORE
VERY, VERY SHORTLY.
THE NAMES OF THOSE VICTIMS,
THOSE 20 KIDS, 18 OF THEM KILLED
IN THE SCHOOL, TWO MORE DIED IN
HOSPITAL.
THERE IS ONE PERSON STILL
WOUNDED.
NICK, WE'LL STAY WITH YOU THIS
MORNING AS YOU LEARN MORE
THROUGH THE COURSE OF IT.
NICK VALENCIA AT THE CNN CENTER
IN ATLANTA.
LET'S GO BACK TO JOHN BERMAN IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WITH ME AT
ANOTHER SITE.
JOHN?
>> GOOD MORNING, ALI, I'M
STANDING IN FRONT OF THE CHURCH
WHERE LAST NIGHT THERE WAS A
VIGIL.
MORE THAN 1,000 PEOPLE GATHERED
HERE WHERE I AM TO GRIEVE
TOGETHER, TO BE TOGETHER, TO
MOURN THOSE LOST.
SO MANY OF THE PEOPLE HERE,
THOUGH, ASKING QUESTIONS, NOT
JUST QUESTIONS ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED AND WHY, BUT WHAT TO DO
NEXT.
PARENTS, TEACHERS, AN ENTIRE
NATION RIGHT NOW STILL
STRUGGLING TO GRASP HOW A GUNMAN
COULD TAKE SO MANY INNOCENT
LIVES AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
SO HOW DO YOU TALK TO YOUR
CHILD?
YOUR CHILD ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED?
OUR LISA SYLVESTER SPOKE TO SOME
EXPERTS.
>> Reporter: IF THERE'S AN IMAGE
THAT SUMS UP THIS STORY, IT IS
THIS.
ANY PARENT OUT THERE CAN RELATE.
PSYCHIATRIST CHARLES RAZEN WITH
THE UNIVERSITY OF ARIZONA'S
COLLEGE OF MEDICINE.
>> HOW DO YOU WRAP YOUR MIND
AROUND SOMETHING LIKE THIS?
WITH A GOOD DEAL OF HEART BREAK
AND WITH THE UNDERSTANDING IT'S
GOING TO TAKE A WHILE AND THAT
THERE WILL BE PEOPLE CLOSELY
IMPACTED BY THIS WHO WILL NEVER
WRAP THEIR MINDS AROUND THIS.
HUMAN MINDS ARE NOT INFINITE.
AND THIS IS -- THIS IS NOW
APPEARING TO BE PROBABLY THE
WORST SCHOOLYARD CATASTROPHE IN
HISTORY.
AND SO THERE'S GOING TO BE A
HUGE LONG-TERM FALLOUT FOR THIS
THAT IS GOING TO ALSO IMPACT
PEOPLE'S EMOTIONAL WELL BEING,
AND WE NEED TO GEAR OURSELVES UP
FOR THAT FALLOUT BECAUSE IT'S
COMING, BECAUSE THIS IS A
HORRIBLE THING.
>> THE NEWS OUT OF NEWTOWN IS
TRAUMATIC FOR PARENTS AND FOR
CHILDREN.
THIS HAPPENED AT A SCHOOL WHERE
KIDS ARE SUPPOSED TO FEEL SAFE.
>> HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN THIS TO
CHILDREN?
WELL, AGAIN, DEPENDS ON THE AGE
OF THE CHILD.
BUT I THINK SIMPLE, FORTHRIGHT
EXPLANATIONS ARE THE BEST.
AND I THINK ONE OF THE THINGS I
TELL CHILDREN IS THERE ARE SOME
BAD PEOPLE IN THE WORLD AND
SOMETIMES BAD PEOPLE DO REALLY
TERRIBLE THINGS.
AND A TERRIBLE THING HAS
HAPPENED AND THERE HAVE BEEN
SOME CHILDREN KILLED AND THIS IS
TERRIBLE, BUT YOU'RE SAFE, AND,
YOU KNOW, YOU'RE SAFE AND YOU'RE
IN A SITUATION NOW WHERE YOU'RE
NOT GOING TO BE HARMED.
>> Reporter: THE AMERICAN
ACADEMY OF PEDIATRICS OFFERS
THIS ADVICE.
TAKE INTO ACCOUNT THE AGE OF THE
CHILD AND PROVIDE BASIC
INFORMATION WITHOUT OFFERING
DETAILS THAT MAY ONLY ALARM
THEM.
ASK YOUR CHILDREN WHAT THEY
ALREADY KNOW AND ANSWER
QUESTIONS.
PARENTS CAN SHARE THEIR OWN
FEELINGS IN THE WAYS THEY'RE
COPING AND FIND MEANINGFUL WAYS
TO HELP OTHERS.
>> CHILDREN ARE RESILIENT.
AND WHAT REALLY MATTERS NOW IS
HOW WE HELP THEM UNDERSTAND
WHAT'S HAPPENED, BUT EVEN MORE
IMPORTANT IS THE SENSE OF
PROTECTION AND SAFETY THAT WE
GIVE THEM STARTING THIS MOMENT
AND FOR THE NEXT WEEKS AND
MONTHS.
>> FOR THOSE WHO WITNESSED THOSE
CHILDREN WHO SAW, THOSE WHO
COVERED THEIR EYES AND EARS TO
SHUT OUT THE HORROR, THEY NEED
TIME, LOVE, AND PRAYERS.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID IT THAT
PARENTS ARE GOING TO GO HOME,
HUG THEIR CHILDREN, AND EVEN TO
PROCESS THIS AS A NATION.
THAT'S JUST GOING TO TAKE TIME.
>> WE'LL BRING YOU MUCH MORE ON
THE SCHOOL SHOOTING TRAGEDY HERE
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, IN JUST
A MOMENT.
BUT FIRST, LET'S GO TO CNN'S
VICTOR BLACKWELL IN ATLANTA FOR
THE LATEST ON OTHER STORIES IN
THE HEADLINES.
>> GOOD MORNING, ALI.
>>> A CONTROVERSIAL REFERENDUM
IS UNDERWAY IN EGYPT RIGHT NOW.
PRESIDENT MOHAMMED MORSI HEADED
TO THE POLLS TODAY TO VOTE ON A
NEW CONSTITUTION FOR HIS
COUNTRY.
HE HAS URGED EGYPTIANS TO
SUPPORT IT, BUT SOME OPPOSITION
PARTIES WANT THEM TO REJECT IT.
THEY FEAR THIS WILL CONSOLIDATE
ISLAMIST POWER AND SAY IT
TRAMPLES ON CIVIL RIGHTS.
>>> THE UNITED STATES HAS GIVEN
THE GO AHEAD TO SEND PATRIOT
ANTI-BALLISTIC MISSILES TO
TURKEY ALONG WITH 400 TROOPS TO
OPERATE THEM.
NOW, THIS MEANS THE U.S. FORCES
FOR THE FIRST TIME WILL BE IN
DIRECT POSITION TO TAKE ACTION
AGAINST THE ASSAD REGIME IN
SYRIA NEXT DOOR.
BUT OFFICIALS SAY THE SURFACE TO
AIR MISSILES ARE FOR DEFENSIVE
PURPOSES ONLY.
>>> AND THIS MAN MAY SOON RETURN
TO POWER AS JAPAN'S NEXT PRIME
MINISTER.
THE HEAD OF JAPAN'S LIBERAL
DEMOCRATIC PARTY.
VOTERS HEAD TO THE POLLS THIS
WEEKEND TO PICK THE NEW
PARLIAMENT.
AND JAPAN'S NEXT GOVERNMENT WILL
FACE A STRUGGLING ECONOMY AND
HEIGHTENED TENSIONS WITH CHINA
AND NORTH KOREA.
>>> IN LONDON, A MASS HAS JUST
BEEN HELD AT WESTMINSTER
CATHEDRAL FOR THE NURSE WHO
APPARENTLY KILLED HERSELF AFTER
SHE TRANSFERRED THAT PRANK CALL
FROM AN AUSTRALIAN RADIO STATION
REGARDING THE DUCHESS OF
CAMBRIDGE.
HER FAMILY ATTENDED THE MASS.
HER CHILDREN SAY THERE IS NOW AN
UNFILLABLE VOID IN THEIR LIVES.
SHE WAS FOUND HANGED LAST WEEK
AND HER DEATH SPARKED AN
INTERNATIONAL OUTCRY.
LET'S GO BACK NOW TO CNN'S ALI
VELSHI IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> THANKS, VICTOR.
AS A FACT, THE TRAGEDY EMERGED
YESTERDAY, 20 PARENTS HAD SOME
OF THE HARDEST NEWS TO HEAR, 20
CHILDREN KILLED IN A VIOLENT
SHOOTING SPREE.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE A LOOK AT
HOW IT ALL UNFOLDED, STARTING
WITH THE FIRST CALL TO POLICE
AND, OF COURSE, IN ABOUT 30
MINUTES, WE ARE EXPECTING THE
NAMES OF THE VICTIMS TO BE
ANNOUNCED AT A NEWS CONFERENCE.
STAY WITH CNN.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
TWINS. I DIDN'T SEE THEM COMING.
I HAVE OBLIGATIONS. CUTE
OBLIGATIONS, BUT OBLIGATIONS.
I NEED TO RETHINK THE
CORE OF MY PORTFOLIO.
WHAT I REALLY NEED IS SLEEP.
INTRODUCING THE ISHARES CORE,
BUILDING BLOCKS FOR THE
HEART OF YOUR PORTFOLIO.
FIND OUT WHY 9 OUT OF 10
LARGE PROFESSIONAL INVESTORS
CHOOSE ISHARES FOR THEIR ETFS.
ISHARES BY BLACKROCK.
CALL 1-800-ISHARES FOR A
PROSPECTUS WHICH INCLUDES
INVESTMENT OBJECTIVES,
RISKS, CHARGES AND EXPENSES.
READ AND CONSIDER
IT CAREFULLY
BEFORE INVESTING.
RISK INCLUDES POSSIBLE
LOSS OF PRINCIPAL.
Since then,
there's been one wedding,
2 kids,
And 43 bottles
of Olay Total Effects.
So in spite of 185 tantrums
378 pre-dawn starts
And a lot of birthdays,
Caroline still looks amazing.
You can challenge
what's possible
Thanks to the trusted
performance of Olay.
60 years, Millions of women,
Real Results.