>>> WE'RE CONTINUING TO FOLLOW
THE AFTERMATH OF THE NEWTOWN
MASSACRE AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
"CNN NEWSROOM" CONTINUES NOW
WITH BROOKE BALDWIN WHO IS IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>>> I'M BROOKE BALDWIN LIVE
TODAY IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
WHERE TODAY THE NEW REALITY IS
SINKING IN.
TODAY PARENTS ARE LIVING
ALONGSIDE AN EMPTY ROOM OF THE
CHILD THEY LOST.
LEFT BEHIND IN THAT ROOM,
PAJAMAS, FAVORITE TOYS, BOOKS
THEY ALWAYS READ TOGETHER,
PARENTS WHO KNOW THIS, EVEN THE
SMELL OF THEIR CHILD'S PILLOW.
AND THESE FIRST RESPONDERS BEING
CALLED HEROES, BUT STILL DAY IN
AND DAY OUT LIVING WITH THE
IMAGES NO ONE COULD HAVE
PREPARED THEM TO SEE.
TODAY, FAMILIES ARE DECIDING ON
COFFINS, HEAD STONES, CHOOSING
SONGS THAT WILL PLAY AT THE
FUNERALS OF FIRST GRADERS.
WANT TO TELL YOU ABOUT THE TWO
LITTLE BOYS WHO ARE ACTUALLY
BEING REMEMBERED RIGHT NOW.
THE FUNERAL FOR 6-YEAR-OLD JACK
PINTO BEGAN JUST ABOUT AN HOUR
AGO.
JACK WILL BE LAID TO REST TODAY
IN NEWTOWN VILLAGE CEMETERY.
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF BACKGROUND
ON THIS 6-YEAR-OLD, JACK ADORED
FOOTBALL, HIS FAVORITE PLAYER
WAS NEW YORK GIANTS RECEIVER
VICTOR CRUZ.
APPARENTLY HE WATCHED GIANTS
GAMES WHILE PROUDLY WEARING HIS
CRUZ JERSEY.
LOOK AT THAT CHEEK.
CRUZ DID PAY TRIBUTE TO HIS
YOUNG FAN BY SCRIBBLING JACK
PINTO, MY HERO.
HERE'S THE CLEAT.
YOU CAN SEE IT.
R.I.P. JACK PINTO.
ON THE OTHER CLEAT DURING THE
GAME ON THE PAST WEEKEND, ON HIS
GLOVE, CRUZ WROTE, JACK PINTO,
THIS ONE IS FOR YOU.
>> IT WAS EMOTIONAL.
I WAS FIGHTING BACK TEARS TO DO
IT.
AND IT FELT, YOU KNOW, FELT
GOOD.
FELT GOOD TO HONOR A FAMILY THAT
WAS GOING THROUGH SO MUCH.
THEY SEEM LIKE A STRONG FAMILY.
I SPOKE TO THE OLDER BROTHER,
AND, YOU KNOW, HE WAS DISTRAUGHT
AS WELL.
COULDN'T SAY MUCH, JUST HOW HIS
BROTHER WAS, YOU KNOW, I WAS HIS
BROTHER'S FAVORITE PLAYER, AND
HE WAS, YOU KNOW, HE WAS
FIGHTING TEARS.
HE COULD BARELY SPEAK TO ME.
>> 6-YEAR-OLD NOAH POZNER WILL
BE LAID TO REST TODAY IN NEARBY
CONNECTICUT.
HIS AUNT SAID, NOAH SOMETIMES
BATTED HIS LONG EYELASHES TO TRY
TO GET WHAT HE WANTED, AND HE
LIT UP EVERYONE'S HEART.
>> NOAH WAS EXTREMELY LIVELY.
HE WAS REALLY THE LIGHT OF THE
ROOM.
HE HAD A HUGE HEART, AND HE WAS
SO MUCH FUN.
A LITTLE BIT RAMBUNCTIOUS, LOTS
OF SPIRIT.
HE LOVED PLAYING WITH ALL OF HIS
COUSINS.
HE LOVED HIS TWIN THE MOST OF
ALL AND ALWAYS SAID HE WAS, YOU
KNOW, THEY WERE BEST FRIENDS.
>> NOAH'S TWIN SISTER, ARIEL,
WENT TO SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
SHE WAS ASSIGNED TO A DIFFERENT
CLASSROOM THAN NOAH, SO SHE
ESCAPED THE CARNAGE.
HIS TWIN SISTER ESCAPED WITH
THEIR 8-YEAR-OLD SISTER, SOPHIA.
WE HAVE BEEN TALKING ABOUT HOW
THESE FAMILIES, ALL AROUND THIS
TOWN AND FAR AWAY, COUNTIES
AWAY, HOW THEY'RE ALL COPING
WITH THIS TRAGEDY FROM FRIDAY
MORNING.
BUT LET ME JUST POINT OUT TO
YOU, ALSO STRUGGLING RIGHT NOW,
THE FIRST RESPONDERS WHO SAW THE
SCENE THEMSELVES, WHO MET THE
PARENTS IN THOSE MOMENTS OF
CONFUSION AND THE SHOCK.
IN FACT, JUST A SHORT TIME AGO,
THE CORONER HERE IN THE TOWN, I
NOTICED SOME WREATHS, 26 WREATHS
BEING DELIVERED HERE, AND I
TALKED TO ONE FIREFIGHTER.
HERE IS HIS STORY.
HOW MANY WREATHS ARE THERE?
>> 26.
>> 26 WREATHS.
WHERE DID THEY GET SENT TO THE
FIREHOUSE?
>> SENT TO THE FIREHOUSE THROUGH
U.P.S.
>> DID YOU KNOW THEY WERE
COMING?
>> NO.
NO, THEY WERE -- THE TRUCK
PULLED UP AND SHE SAID I HAVE A
DELIVERY OF 26 WREATHS.
WE UNLOADED THEM ALL AND FIGURED
WE WOULD COME UP WITH A PLACE TO
PUT THEM, TRY TO KEEP THEM ALL
TOGETHER, SHIPPED ALL FWRWAY FR
OREGON.
>> HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN HERE?
>> SINCE FRIDAY.
>> WHERE ARE YOU BASED OUT OF.
>> SANDY HOOK FIREHOUSE.
>> HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN AT
FIREHOUSE?
>> WE'RE GOING HOME TONIGHT TO
SLEEP, BUT --
>> BUT YEARS, HOW MANY YEARS.
>> YEARS.
SINCE HIGH SCHOOL.
I'M 38.
>> SINCE HIGH SCHOOL AND YOU'RE
38.
DID YOU EVER IN A MILLION YEARS
THINK YOU WOULD BE EXPERIENCING
THIS IN YOUR LITTLE TOWN?
>> NOBODY IN THIS TOWN WOULD
EVER THINK THAT.
>> WHERE WERE YOU WHEN YOU
HEARD?
>> WORKING, WORK ACROSS TOWN.
WE SAW THE HELICOPTERS.
>> WHEN YOU SAW THE HELICOPTERS,
WHAT DID YOU THINK IT WAS?
>> NOT ON THE SCALE IT WAS.
ONE OR TWO.
WE HEARD THE PRINCIPAL AT FIRST
AND -- AS TIME WENT ON, WE GOT
THE REPORTS.
AND JUST DIDN'T BELIEVE IT AND
CAME DOWN THE ROAD, IT WAS JUST
ALL SURREAL.
SEEING ALL THE CARS, ALL THIS.
IT'S TOUGH.
>> WHERE DID YOU GO ONCE YOU SAW
THE CARS?
STRAIGHT TO THE FIREHOUSE?
>> STRAIGHT TO THE FIREHOUSE.
FROM THERE, WE JUST --
>> HELP US AROUND THE WORLD
UNDERSTAND WHAT YOU, AS A FIRST
RESPONDER, ARE GOING THROUGH.
>> SADNESS, ANGER, GUILT IN SOME
ASPECTS.
>> WHY GUILT?
WHAT COULD YOU HAVE DONE?
>> EXACTLY.
WE WERE HAVING COUNSELING.
AS A GROUP.
>> CAN I GET YOUR FIRST AND LAST
NAME?
>> NAME'S JEFFREY THOMAS.
>> JEFFREY THOMAS.
SINCE HIGH SCHOOL.
WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF THE PREETHS,
JU
WREATHS, PEOPLE YOU DON'T KNOW
SENDING YOU ALL THESE WREATHS TO
PUT UP IN TOWN.
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY TO THE PEOPLE
OF PORTLAND, OREGON?
>> THANK YOU.
IT MAKES US FEEL WARM TO KNOW
THIS IS -- IT IS AMAZING THAT
PEOPLE THAT FAR AWAY CARE ABOUT
US.
>> TWO SIMPLE WORDS, THANK YOU.
AND WE HAVE ALSO NOW LEARNED
THAT THE U.S. SENATE, MEMBERS OF
THE SENATE, HAVE OBSERVED A
MOMENT OF SILENCE.
WANT TO TAKE A MOMENT HERE, TAKE
A LOOK.
>> I NOW ASK THAT THE UNITED
STATES SENATE OBSERVE A MOMENT
OF SILENCE TO HONOR THE VICTIMS
OF THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL TRAGEDY.
>> MR. PRESIDENT --
>> MAJORITY LEADER.
>> THE FOLLOWING REMARKS --
>> JUST WANTED TO SHARE THAT
MOMENT WITH YOU AS WE JUST
LEARNED THAT THE FLOOR OF THE
U.S. SENATE IN SILENCE, IN
MEMORY OF THE LOST LIVES HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
LET ME ALSO KEEP YOU UP TO SPEED
IN TERMS OF THE INVESTIGATION, A
POSSIBLE MOTIVE.
WE HAVE NEW DETAILS FROM POLICE
THAT MAY COMPLICATE THE SEARCH
FOR A MOTIVE.
>> THERE WAS NO CONNECTION
BETWEEN THE SHOOTER AND THE
SCHOOL ACCORDING TO THE SCHOOL
AUTHORITIES HERE IN NEWTOWN.
>> NONE AT ALL?
>> ACCORDING TO THE SCHOOL
AUTHORITIES IN NEWTOWN.
>> WE HAVE ALSO LEARNED ABOUT
ANOTHER SURVIVOR OF FRIDAY'S
MASSACRE.
POLICE SAY NOW NOT ONE, TWO
ADULTS WERE SHOT AND WOUNDED AT
THE SCHOOL, BOTH ADULTS NOW
RECOVERING FROM INJURIES.
I WANT TO BRING IN DON LEMON WHO
HAS BEEN HERE FOR A COUPLE OF
DAYS HERE IN NEWTOWN.
LET ME ASK YOU FIRST, JUST ABOUT
NANCY LANZA, THE GUNMAN'S
MOTHER.
YOU'VE TALKED TO FRIENDS WHO
KNEW HER, WHAT DID THEY SHARE
WITH YOU?
>> THEY APPROACHED ME THE OTHER
NIGHT BECAUSE THEY SAID THEY
WERE HEARING SOME THINGS IN THE
MEDIA THAT THEY JUST -- THAT
JUST DIDN'T RING TRUE TO THEM
ABOUT NANCY LANZA AND PEOPLE
WERE IN SOME WAY, THEY FELT,
MAYBE BLAMING HER FOR WHAT
HAPPENED.
THEY SAID, YES, YOU KNOW, THEY
SAID THAT THE SHOOTER DID HAVE
ASPERGER'S SYNDROME AND THAT HE,
YOU KNOW, HE WAS SOMEONE -- A
KID WHO KEPT TO HIMSELF, BUT
THEY SAY SHE WAS A RESPONSIBLE
MOTHER AND IN THEIR ESTIMATION A
GOOD MOTHER.
FOUR OF HER FRIENDS I TALKED TO
WHO ALL APPROACHED ME AND SAID,
WE NEED TO TALK ABOUT THIS
WOMAN, BECAUSE SHE IS AMONG THE
VICTIMS AND QUITE FRANKLY THIS
IS A HORRIBLE THING, UNDENIABLE
WHAT HAPPENED TO THE KIDS, BUT
THEY LOVED HER AND THEY WANT
PEOPLE TO KNOW ABOUT HER.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> TELL US ABOUT NANCY, WE DON'T
KNOW MUCH ABOUT HER.
>> NANCY WAS JUST A LOVELY
WOMAN.
A GREAT FRIEND, YOU KNOW, WARM
PERSONALITY.
YOU KNOW, SHE WOULD JUST MAKE
YOU SMILE WHEN SHE WALKED INTO
THE ROOM.
>> YOU SAID YOU WANTED TO TALK
ABOUT HER BECAUSE THERE ARE SOME
THINGS YOU WANTED TO CLEAR UP.
>> WELL, I'VE SEEN A LOT OF
THINGS IN THE MEDIA ABOUT HER
BEING THIS SURVIVALIST WACKO AND
THAT WAS NOT HER AT ALL.
SHE WAS -- SHE DID HAVE GUNS,
WHICH SHE USED VERY RESPONSIBLY.
SHE WENT SHOOTING WITH MUTUAL
FRIEND OF OURS WHO IS A RETIRED
NEW YORK CITY POLICE OFFICER.
SO, YOU KNOW, HE TAUGHT HER HOW
TO SHOOT, SHE WAS VERY
RESPONSIBLE WITH THE GUN.
SHE WAS VERY RESPONSIBLE PERSON
IN GENERAL.
ESPECIALLY IN TERMS OF SAFETY.
>> AND SHE TOOK THE BOYS TO THE
SHOOTING RANGE.
THAT'S BEEN TALKED ABOUT.
SHE DID TAKE THEM TO THE
SHOOTING RANGE.
>> FROM WHAT I UNDERSTAND, YES.
>> AND WHAT DID YOU WANT TO SAY
ABOUT THAT?
>> AGAIN, I GUESS I WANT TO JUST
MIMIC RUSS AS FAR AS HER SAFETY.
NANCY WOULDN'T EVEN ANSWER A
PHONE OR A TEXT OR EVEN LOOK AT
HER TEXT IN THE CAR.
IF I GOT IN HER CAR, IT WAS
OOPS, SEAT BELT, AT THE FIRST
DING.
OR BEFORE THE DING HAPPENED.
SO SHE WAS JUST VERY CAREFUL AND
CAUTIOUS AND RESPONSIBLE.
AND IN REGARD TO, YOU KNOW,
LEAVING ANYTHING OUT, AS FAR AS
A GUN, JUST -- I CAN'T BELIEVE
THAT SHE WOULD DO THAT.
>> SEBASTIAN, WHAT DO YOU THINK?
TELL US ABOUT YOUR MEMORY.
>> MY MEMORIES OF HER, SHE WAS A
VERY DIGNIFIED WOMAN.
SHE HAD A LOT OF CLASS.
VERY PROPER.
HAD A GREAT MORAL COMPASS.
WE JUST SAW HER, WHAT, THREE
WEEKS AGO, MY PLACE, AND I LEFT
AND DIDN'T SAY BYE AND SHE SENDS
ME A TEXT, YOU DIDN'T SAY BYE TO
ME.
THAT'S THE KIND OF PERSON SHE
WAS.
POLITE AND NICE TO YOU.
JUST A REALLY GOOD PERSON.
>> AND, BROOKE, THEY SAID,
CONTRARY TO WHAT PEOPLE HAD BEEN
SAYING, SHE DID NOT WORK FOR THE
SCHOOL, DID NOT VOLUNTEER FOR
THE SCHOOL.
SHE WAS THINKING OF MOVING
BECAUSE SHE WANTED TO FIND A
FOUR-YEAR COLLEGE SO HE COULD
HAVE AS NORMAL AN ADULT LIFE AS
POSSIBLE.
>> WE'RE LEARNING MORE HIM AND
SOME OF THE OTHER VICTIMS.
I WANT TO TALK ABOUT, WE WERE
HERE LAST NIGHT, FOR THE
PRESIDENT, THIS TOWN WAS PACKED,
DIFFICULT TO MOVE AROUND, JUST
BECAUSE WHEN THE PRESS PRESIDENT
IS IN TOWN, SECURITY IS
DIFFICULT.
I WANT TO TALK ABOUT THE
GOVERNOR HERE, DAN MALLOY, HE
SAID SOMETHING POIGNANT, USED
THIS IMAGERY, IT IS COLD AND
WE'RE CLOSE TO WINTER AND LISTEN
TO WHAT HE SAID ABOUT THE
SNOWFALL.
>> LET ME ASSURE YOU THAT IN
WINTER EACH TIME I SEE THE
BEGINNING OF A SNOWFALL, WILL BE
THINKING OF THOSE 27 SOULS LOST
JUST A FEW DAYS AGO.
EACH TIME THE DAY GETS A LITTLE
LONGER, I WILL THINK AND DREAM
OF THE LIVES THAT MIGHT HAVE
BEEN AND THE LIVES THAT WERE SO
FULL OF GRACE.
AND WHEN THE FLOWERS START TO
COME OUT OF THE GROUND, AND WHEN
THEY RISE UP, I WILL KNOW THAT
WE ARE IN TOUCH WITH THOSE THAT
WE HAVE LOST IN THE LAST FEW
DAYS.
>> IT GIVES YOU GOOSEBUMPS
LISTENING TO IT AGAIN.
AS WE WERE WATCHING FROM OUR
LIVE TRUCK, WATCHING THEM, THAT
MEMORIAL AND WATCHING THE
GOVERNOR, THE SNOW STARTED TO
FALL.
>> AFTER THAT MEMORIAL.
>> THE SNOW STARTED TO FALL.
>> ISN'T THAT AMAZING?
THE WEATHER HAS BEEN INDICATIVE
OF THE WAY PEOPLE FEEL, DREARY,
COLD AND WET.
SOME PEOPLE SAY IT IS SYNONYMOUS
WITH TEARS.
I THINK THE WHOLE COUNTRY,
AMERICA'S HEART IS BROKEN AT
THIS POINT.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
DON, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
WE'LL TALK A LITTLE LATER.
AND I KNOW A LOT OF YOU ARE
REACHING OUT TO US, TO CNN, HOW
YOU CAN HELP THE PEOPLE HERE
AFFECTED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
GO TO CNN.COM/IMPACT.
CNN.COM/IMPACT TO LEARN HOW YOU
CAN GIVE.
OF COURSE, SCHOOLS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY ARE ON HEIGHTENED ALERT
NOW AFTER NEWTOWN'S TRAGEDY.
WE'RE GOING TO TALK TO ONE
EXPERT ABOUT WHETHER CURRENT
TACTICS, WHAT IS GOING ON IN
SCHOOLS TODAY, DRILLS YOUR
CHILDREN MAY BE GOING THROUGH,
SHOULD THEY BE CHANGED INCLUDING
WHETHER STUDENTS SHOULD EVER
FIGHT BACK.
It's hard to see opportunity
in today's challenging
environment.
Unless you have the right
perspective.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
has the vision
and experience to look beyond
the obvious.
We'll uncover opportunities,
find hidden risk,
and make success a reality.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
>>> ONE OF THE FIRST DETAILS
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE GAVE
ABOUT THE MASS KILLING HERE IN
NEWTOWN, AS SOON AS OFFICERS GOT
TO SANDY HOOK, THEY WENT RIGHT
INTO THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> ON AND OFF DUTY TROOPERS
RESPONDED TO THE CALL AND WITH
POLICE IMMEDIATELY UPON ARRIVAL
ENTERED THE SCHOOL AND BEGAN A
COMPLETE ACTIVE SHOOTER SEARCH
OF THE BUILDING.
>> THAT IS A TOTAL SWITCH IN
TACTICS AND LAW ENFORCERS SAY
WHEN IT COMES TO WHAT THEY
LEARNED IN 1999, IN LITTLETON,
COLORADO, THE COLUMBINE HIGH
SCHOOL SHOOTING, OFFICERS THERE
WERE HEAVILY CRITICIZED FOR NOT
ENTERING THE BUILDING AS THEY
WAITED FOR S.W.A.T. TEAMS TO
ARRIVE.
WE HAVE LEARNED FROM THE PAST,
WHAT ABOUT THE FUTURE?
WHAT WILL SCHOOLS DO IN THE WAKE
OF WHAT HAPPENED HERE IN NEWTOWN
ON FRIDAY MORNING?
KEN TRUMP IS FROM THE NATIONAL
SCHOOL SAFETY AND SECURITY
SERVICES WHICH HELPS SCHOOL
DISTRICTS ACROSS THE COUNTRY,
SECURITY AND EMERGENCY
PREPAREDNESS.
SO, KEN, WELCOME TO YOU.
I KNOW YOU ARE HERE IN NEWTOWN,
YOURSELF.
JUST OFF THE TOP HERE, WHAT WERE
YOUR IMPRESSIONS OF WHAT YOU SAW
AND EXPERIENCED?
>> MINE STARTED AS A FATHER.
I WAS ON MY KID'S PLAYGROUND,
SUPERVISING, VOLUNTEERING AT
RECESS TIME, AND 25 YEARS OF
SCHOOL SAFETY EXPERIENCE WENT
OUT THE DOOR AS A PUNCH IN THE
GUT WHEN YOU HEAR IT OCCURRED AT
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AND WHEN I WAS IN NEWTOWN, I
FOUND IT REALLY HARD TO ASK
ANYBODY WHAT DO YOU ASK PEOPLE?
WE KNOW HOW THEY FEEL.
I THINK THAT IT'S SUCH A
LONG-TERM RECOVERY PROCESS.
WE KNOW FROM OTHER HIGH PROFILE
INCIDENTS.
AND I THINK ANOTHER CONCERN IS
THE PARENTS ACROSS THE COUNTRY
ARE ALARMED FROM -- ABOUT ASKING
QUESTIONS BECAUSE OUR MOST
VULNERABLE CHILDREN HAVE NOW
BECOME A TARGET IN ONE OF OUR
SCHOOLS AND PEOPLE ARE CONCERNED
ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
BUT THEY SHOULD SEND THEIR KIDS
TO SCHOOL.
>> KEN, THOUGH, LET ME ASK YOU,
AS WE'RE HEARING THE STORIES
FROM THIS PRINCIPAL IN
PARTICULAR, WHO JUST INSTALLED
THIS NEW SECURITY SYSTEM, YOU
HAD TO RING THE DOORBELL IF YOU
WERE COMING TO THE SCHOOL AFTER
9:30 IN THE MORNING.
YOU KNOW, THEY SEEM TO BE DOING
ALL THE RIGHT THINGS HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
WHAT IS THE TAKEAWAY FOR SCHOOLS
MOVING FORWARD?
IS IN A TAKEAWAY?
>> I WANT TO PROPOSE A DIFFERENT
WAY OF LOOKING AT THIS SLIGHTLY.
SADLY THE OUTCOME WAS TRAGIC.
THE NEW SECURITY SYSTEM PEOPLE
HAVE SAID DIDN'T FAIL.
I WOULD SAY THAT IT -- WE
CERTAINLY DIDN'T HAVE THE
DESIRED OUTCOME WITH NO LIVES
LOST.
BUT A SECURITY SYSTEM WILL
EITHER DETER THOSE WHO ARE
DETERRABLE OR DELAY OTHERS.
AND I WOULD LIKE TO BELIEVE IT
DELAYED EVEN IN SECONDS THE
SHOOTER, AND THAT IT GAVE AN
OPPORTUNITY FOR SOME KIDS TO GET
TO A SAFE PLACE.
I THINK THAT ANY TECHNOLOGY IS
AN EXTRA TOOL, BUT WE TEND TO
LOOK FOR A QUICK FIX.
TECHNOLOGY IS GOING TO DETER OR
DELAY.
A SECOND -- SECONDS CAN MEAN THE
MOST VALUABLE TIME.
BUT I THINK LOOK AT THE HUMAN
ASPECT BEHIND IT.
YOU HAVE A PRINCIPAL AND A
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST WHO DIDN'T
RUN FROM THE GUNMAN, BUT WENT TO
PROTECT THE CHILDREN.
YOU HAVE TEACHERS WHO KNEW TO
LOCK DOWN, STAFF TRAINED, THE
SECURITY SYSTEM.
THERE ARE MANY OF THE BEST
PRACTICES IN PLACE THAT WERE
IMPLEMENTED.
I DON'T KNOW WE NEED TO TOTALLY
THROW OUT THE PLAYBOOK.
I KNOW WE NEED TO CONTINUE TO
FOCUS ON THE FUNDAMENTALS AND
ALSO LOOK AT RESOURCES THAT ARE
DEDICATED TO SECURITY, WHICH
HAVE BEEN CUT BACK IN RECENT
YEARS.
>> WELL, KEN, LET ME BRING YOU
BACK TO YOUR POINT, THOUGH YOU
POINT OUT WHAT THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST AND THE PRINCIPAL
WERE SORT OF LUNGING AT THIS
GUNMAN.
I READ AN ARTICLE THAT DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG, THE PRINCIPAL, WAS
SHOUTING BACK AT A TEACHER DOWN
THE HALL, CLOSE THE DOOR, LOCK
IT FROM THE INSIDE.
WHAT IS PROPER PROTOCOL, HEAVEN
FORBID SOMETHING ELSE HAPPENS
DOWN THE ROAD, WHAT SHOULD
TEACHERS, WHAT SHOULD STUDENTS
DO?
SHOULD THEY FIGHT BACK?
SHOULD THEY RUN?
OR SHOULD THEY HIDE?
>> WELL, I THINK THAT THERE ARE
GOING TO BE NATURAL INSTINCTS
THAT KICK IN AS IT DID WITH THE
PRINCIPALS AND WE HAVE SEEN
ELSEWHERE WITH TEACHERS WHO HAVE
STEPPED IN FRONT OF A BULLET,
WHO TACKLED GUNMAN AND TAKEN
OTHER ACTIONS BASED ON THE
SCENARIO AT HAND.
THE BEST PRACTICES HAVE INCLUDED
TO PRACTICE LOCKDOWNS, DOING
EVACUATIONS, CERTAINLY SOME WHO
HAVE BEEN INSTINCTIVELY GOT OUT
OF HARM'S WAY.
I THINK WE'RE STEPPING INTO SOME
DANGEROUS AREA IF WE START
TALKING ABOUT TEACHING
ELEMENTARY KIDS TO THROW BOOK
BAGS AND BACKPACKS AT ARMED
INTRUDERS WHO COME IN BECAUSE
THERE ARE ALSO SITUATIONS THAT
AREN'T ACTIVE SHOOTERS, BUT
HOSTAGE SITUATIONS.
SO DO YOU HAVE ONE KID STAND UP,
THROW A PENCIL AND THEN GET SHOT
AND KILLED BY SOMEONE WHO MAY
HAVE BEEN A HOSTAGE TAKER THAT
COULD HAVE BEEN RESOLVED.
LO
LOTS OF QUESTIONS.
HOW DO YOU IMPLEMENT SOMETHING
LIKE THAT?
I THINK THAT WE NEED TO FOCUS ON
A LOT OF THE FUNDAMENTALS, BUT
AND SEE IF WE CAN IMPROVE, BUT I
THINK WE ALSO HAVE TO LOOK AT
IMPLEMENTATION AND AGE
APPROPRIATENESS AND OTHER
FACTORS AS WELL.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
I'M SURE THESE ARE CONVERSATIONS
BEING HAD ACROSS THE COUNTRY
TODAY AND IN THE COMING DAYS IN
THE WAKE OF WHAT HAPPENED HERE
ON FRIDAY AMONG SCHOOL
ADMINISTRATORS, TEACHERS AND
PARENTS ACROSS THE DINNER TABLES
WITH THEIR LITTLE KIDS.
KEN TRUMP, THANK YOU FOR JOINING
ME.
I APPRECIATE IT.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> WE'LL BE BACK IN JUST A
MOMENT.
LOOK, IF YOU HAVE COPD LIKE ME,
YOU KNOW IT CAN BE HARD TO
BREATHE, AND HOW THAT FEELS.
COPD INCLUDES CHRONIC
BRONCHITIS AND EMPHYSEMA.
SPIRIVA HELPS CONTROL
MY COPD SYMPTOMS
BY KEEPING MY AIRWAYS
OPEN FOR 24 HOURS.
PLUS, IT REDUCES COPD FLARE-UPS.
SPIRIVA IS THE ONLY ONCE-DAILY
INHALED COPD MAINTENANCE
TREATMENT THAT DOES BOTH.
SPIRIVA HANDIHALER TIOTROPIUM
BROMIDE INHALATION POWDER
DOES NOT REPLACE FAST-ACTING
INHALERS FOR SUDDEN SYMPTOMS.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU HAVE
KIDNEY PROBLEMS, GLAUCOMA,
TROUBLE URINATING, OR
AN ENLARGED PROSTATE.
THESE MAY WORSEN WITH SPIRIVA.
DISCUSS ALL MEDICINES
YOU TAKE, EVEN EYE DROPS.
STOP TAKING SPIRIVA AND SEEK
IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
IF YOUR BREATHING
SUDDENLY WORSENS,
YOUR THROAT OR TONGUE
SWELLS, YOU GET HIVES,
VISION CHANGES OR EYE PAIN,
OR PROBLEMS PASSING URINE.
OTHER SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE
DRY MOUTH AND CONSTIPATION.
NOTHING CAN REVERSE COPD.
SPIRIVA HELPS ME BREATHE BETTER.
(BLOWING SOUND)
ASK YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT SPIRIVA.
>>> I'M JOHN BERMAN LIVE IN NEW
YORK.
BACK TO NEW TOWTOWN IN A MOMENT.
>>> SYRIA'S VICE PRESIDENT IS
REPORTEDLY CALLING FOR A
NATIONAL UNITY GOVERNMENT WITH
WIDE POWERS TO BRING ABOUT AN
END TO THAT COUNTRY'S CIVIL WAR.
THE COMMENTS COME AS A FRESH
ROUND OF VIOLENCE SHAKES SYRIA.
SAID TO BE TAKEN AFTER SYRIAN
GOVERNMENT PLANES BOMBED A
PALESTINIAN REFUGEE CAMP NEAR
DAMASCUS ON SUNDAY.
A UK-BASED HUMAN RIGHTS GROUP
SAYS AT LEAST EIGHT PEOPLE WERE
KILLED THERE.
MEANWHILE, VICE PRESIDENT FAROUK
AL SHARIA TOLD THE LEBANESE
NEWSPAPER THAT NEITHER THE
REBELS NOR THE CURRENT
GOVERNMENT HAS THE ABILITY TO
REACH AN END POINT.
AN OPPOSITION GROUP SAYS AT
LEAST 150 PEOPLE WERE KILLED
ACROSS SYRIA ON SUNDAY.
>>> SOUTH CAROLINA GOVERNOR
NIKKI HALEY ANNOUNCED THAT
CONGRESSMAN TIM SCOTT WILL
REPLACE OUTGOING SENATOR JIM
DeMINT.
HALEY SAID SHE WAS LOOKING FOR A
CONSERVATIVE FIGHTER.
HE THANKED HIS MOTHER FOR NOT
QUITTING ON HIM.
>> WHEN YOU START OUT IN A
SINGLE PARENT HOUSEHOLD WITH A
MOM WHO WORKS 16 HOURS A DAY,
AND YOU'RE LOOKING AT A FUTURE
THAT DOESN'T LOOK AS BRIGHT AND
YOU'RE LIVING IN CHARLESTON,
SOUTH CAROLINA, YOU BUILD THE
STRENGTH THAT COMES FROM HAVING
APPRECIATION AND UNDERSTANDING
THAT IT IS NOT ABOUT YOU, THAT
IT IS ABOUT YOUR FAITH, ABOUT
YOUR FAMILY, AND I LOVE MY
MOTHER WHO IS HERE WITH ME,
FRANCIS SCOTT.
>> GOVERNOR HALEY PRAISED THE
OUTGOING SENATOR JIM DeMINT
CALLING HIM A CONSERVATIVE ROCK
STAR.
SCOTT TAKES THE REINS IN JANUARY
WHEN DeMINT LEAVES TO LEAD THE
HERITAGE FOUNDATION.
>>> WE HAVE A BIG STORY COMING
OUT OF THE WHITE HOUSE THIS
AFTERNOON.
THE PRESIDENT MET AGAIN TODAY
WITH HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER
AFTER BOEHNER MADE TWO APPARENT
CONCUSSIESSIONS TOWARD AVERTING
SO-CALLED FISCAL CLIFF.
THIS MEETING WAS 45 MINUTES LONG
THIS TIME.
OVER THE WEEKEND, THE SPEAKER
PROPOSED RAISING TAX RATES ON
THOSE MAKING OVER A MILLION
DOLLARS A YEAR.
CNN HAS LEARNED HE'S ALSO
PROPOSING A ONE-YEAR EXTENSION
OF THE GOVERNMENT'S BORROWING
LIMIT, WHICH COULD AVERT YET
ANOTHER UGLY DEBT CEILING
DEBATE.
MEANWHILE, CONGRESSIONAL SOURCE
TELLS US IN EXCHANGE, SPEAKER
BOEHNER IS PUSHING FOR A
TRILLION DOLLARS IN SPENDING
CUTS INCLUDING TO MEDICARE,
WHICH SO FAR THE WHITE HOUSE HAS
OPPOSED, AND FOR NOW THE
PRESIDENT IS ALSO HOLDING FAST
TO HIS DESIRE TO RAISE TAX RATES
ON INCOMES BEGINNING AT
$250,000.
A LOT LESS THAN THE MILLION
DOLLARS SPEAKER BANER IS P ERBO
PROPOSING NOW.
BROOKE, BACK TO YOU IN NEWTOWN.
>>> BACK HERE LIVE IN NEWTOWN ON
THIS MONDAY, THE TRAGEDY HERE IN
CONNECTICUT, IT HAS MANY
AMERICANS DEBATING GUN LAWS.
AND TODAY ONE SENATOR, WHO IS A
GUN OWNER, IS MAKING SOME
SURPRISING COMMENTS ABOUT WHAT
CONGRESS SHOULD DO VERY SOON.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS SHELDON, WHOSE LONG DY
SETTING UP THE NEWS
STARTS WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND A CHOICE.
TAKE TYLENOL OR TAKE ALEVE,
THE #1 RECOMMENDED PAIN
RELIEVER BY ORTHOPEDIC DOCTORS.
JUST TWO ALEVE
CAN KEEP PAIN AWAY ALL DAY.
BACK TO THE NEWS.
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAND.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
>>> THIS IS NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
AND THIS IS THE WEEK THE
FUNERALS BEGIN.
IN FACT, ONE IS BEGINNING JUST
ACROSS THE STREET.
THIS IS THE ONLY UNDERTAKER IN
THIS TOWN OF SOME 27,000 PEOPLE.
HE'S BEEN QUOTED AS SAYING, THIS
IS A WEEK FROM HELL.
HE'S FACED WITH THE DAUNTING
TASK OF MASKING SOME OF THE
WOUNDS FROM FRIDAY'S SHOOTING.
AND WE'RE TOLD, THINK ABOUT THE
TINY CASKETS, SOME WILL BE OPEN,
SOME WILL BE CLOSED.
WHAT IS HAPPENING ALL AROUND ME
IS THE FIREFIGHTERS HERE AT
SANDY HOOK FIRE AND RESCUE,
THEY'RE UNWRAPPING WREATHS FROM
ALL THE WAY ACROSS THE COUNTRY
IN PORTLAND, OREGON.
THERE ARE 20 FOR THE LITTLE
LIVES LOST.
JUST DRIVING AROUND NEWTOWN, YOU
GET THE SENSE OF COMMUNITY AND
YOU SEE THESE MEMORIALS POPPING
UP, LIKE THIS ONE, WE LOVE YOU,
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY, HONK IF
YOU LOVE US TOO.
SIGNS, GOD BLESS OUR TOWN.
PRAY FOR OUR TOWN.
WE NOTICED IN THE MIDDLE OF PART
OF TOWN, THE BIG FLAG IS NOW
FLYING AT HALF-STAFF.
THIS IS THE FIREHOUSE HERE WHERE
A LOT OF THE FAMILIES HUDDLED
FRIDAY MORNING, LEARNING THE
FATES OF THEIR LITTLE SONS AND
DAUGHTERS.
WE CAN'T CROSS THE STREET.
YOU CAN SEE THE SIGN HERE, NO
MEDIA BEYOND THIS POINT.
WE CAN'T GET INSIDE THE
FIREHOUSE.
MANY OF THESE FIRST RESPONDERS
STILL VERY MUCH STILL REELING
OVER WHAT THEY SAW, WHAT THEY
RESPONDED TO ON FRIDAY.
WANT TO READ YOU A QUOTE, FROM A
VOLUNTEER FIREFIGHTER, 39 YEARS
HERE, HE SAID, I'VE SEEN SOME
HORRENDOUS THINGS IN 39 YEARS AS
A FIREFIGHTER.
THIS IS THE FIRST TIME I WENT
HOME AND CRIED.
I DID MANAGE TO TALK TO TWO
YOUNGER FIREFIGHTERS HERE AND
THEY TOLD ME REALLY THE
PRIORITY, BEYOND THE COMMUNITY,
GRIEF COUNSELORS TO HELP THEM
COPE WITH WHAT THEY SAW.
BACK HERE LIVE, JUST TALKING TO
DIFFERENT PEOPLE IN AND AROUND
THE COMMUNITY AND YOUR HEART
BREAKS FOR THEM.
AND A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE
WONDERING IF WHAT HAS HAPPENED
HERE WILL CHANGE THE DEBATE OVER
GUN CONTROL.
PRESIDENT OBAMA HASN'T OFFERED
SPECIFICS AS TO WHAT HE WILL DO.
BUT MADE IT CLEAR, HE WANTS TO
PREVENT FUTURE TRAGEDIES LIKE
THIS ONE.
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT, TO MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS, TO PARENTS
AND EDUCATORS IN AN EFFORT AIMED
AT PREVENTING MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS.
>> THAT WAS THE PRESIDENT
SPEAKING LAST NIGHT AT THE HIGH
SCHOOL HERE.
BUT I WANT TO LET YOU KNOW WHAT
A DEMOCRATIC SENATOR FROM WEST
VIRGINIA, HERE IS WHAT JOE
MANCHIN SAID.
HE'S WEIGHING IN AS WELL.
HE'S A GUN OWNER FROM A RURAL
STATE, FULL OF HUNTERS LIKE
HIMSELF.
SO THIS MORNING HE SAID THAT
WHEN IT COMES TO GUN CONTROL, IT
IS TIME FOR EVERYONE TO JOIN THE
DISCUSSION.
>> WE HAVE GOT TO SIT DOWN.
I ASK ALL MY FRIENDS IN THE NRA
AND I'M A PROUD NRA MEMBER AND
ALWAYS HAVE BEEN, WE NEED TO SIT
DOWN AND MOVE THIS DIALOGUE TO A
REASONABLE APPROACH TO FIXING
IT.
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE ON THE
TABLE AND I THINK IT WILL BE.
>> IN THE WEST, A LOT OF GUN
SHOW CUSTOMERS HAVE NEWTOWN ON
THEIR MINDS AND THEY HAVE THEIR
OWN IDEAS AS TO HOW THE
SHOOTINGS COULD HAVE BEEN
PREVENTED.
HERE IS CNN'S CASEY WIAN.
>> CLM BYOLUMBINE, VIRGINIA TEC
SIKH TEMPLE IN WISCONSIN, AN
OREGON SHOPPING MALL, EVEN WITH
THE MASS SHOOTINGS IT HAS BECOME
EASIER FOR MOST AMERICANS TO
CARRY A GUN, OWN AN ASSAULT
RIFLE OR USE HIGH CAPACITY
MAGAZINES.
BUT IN THE AFTERMATH OF
CONNECTICUT, VOICES, MOST
NOTABLY FROM A TEARFUL PRESIDENT
OBAMA, ARE CALLING FOR TIGHTER
GUN CONTROL.
YOU WON'T HEAR THEM AT A
CALIFORNIA GUN SHOW HELD THE DAY
AFTER THE CONNECTICUT MASSACRE.
>> EVERYBODY IS IN A PANIC.
I'VE NEVER SEEN SO MANY PEOPLE
AT A GUN SHOW.
I THINK THEY'RE WORRIED ABOUT
THEIR SECOND AMENDMENT RIGHTS.
>> Reporter: THERE IS SYMPATHY
FOR THE VICTIMS.
>> IT IS HORRIBLE THAT THOSE
CHILDREN DID DIE.
>> Reporter: BUT THE SOLUTION
HERE, MORE GUNS.
>> IF ONE OF THOSE TEACHERS, ONE
OF THEM, A FACULTY MEMBER, A
JANITOR, HAD A GUN, BAM, HE
WOULD HAVE KILLED AN EIGHTH,
NOTHING COMPARED TO WHAT HE WAS
CAPABLE OF DOING.
YOU HAVE TO ALLOW US TO PROTECT
OURSELVES.
>> THE GUNS REALLY DIDN'T KILL
PEOPLE.
IT WAS THE PERSON WHO WAS CRAZY.
HE WAS MENTALLY UNSTABLE.
>> Reporter: COLORADO GOVERNOR
JOHN HICKENLOOPER SAID TWO DAYS
BEFORE THE CONNECTICUT SHOOTING
IT IS TIME TO CONSIDER GUN
CONTROL LEGISLATION.
BUT ACKNOWLEDGES IT WILL BE
DIFFICULT.
>> I TOOK MY SON, 10-YEAR-OLD
SON OUT SHOOTING CLAY PIGEONS TO
TWO WEEKS AGO.
THAT PART OF IT, THAT PART OF
GUN CULTURE IS SO DEEPLY
ENGRAINED IN COLORADO.
IN THE UNITED STATES.
LITERALLY ALMOST EVERYWHERE THAT
TO TRY AND CHANGE IT WOULD BE,
YOU KNOW, WOULD BE A VERY
DIFFICULT THING.
>> Reporter: THERE IS A
PRECEDENT.
GREAT BRITAIN BANNED NEARLY ALL
HANDGUNS AFTER A SHOOTING IN
1996.
OUT OF MESA, ARIZONA, ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, PARENTS REFLECTED.
>> SHOULD BE MORE GUN CONTROL,
YES.
>> Reporter: WHY DO YOU THINK
THAT?
>> WELL, GUNS ARE -- GUNS ARE IN
THE WRONG HANDS ARE VERY
DANGEROUS.
>> GUNS DON'T KILL PEOPLE.
PEOPLE KILL PEOPLE.
>> DEFINITELY SHOULD BE A GUN
CONTROL.
SHOULDN'T BE NO GUNS OUT THERE,
YOU KNOW.
A LOT OF CRAZY PEOPLE DON'T KNOW
HOW TO HANDLE GUNS.
>> I DON'T THINK TAKING GUNS OUT
OF CIVILIANS WHO ARE GOOD,
CONTRIBUTING MEMBERS OF SOCIETY
ARE THE ANSWER.
>> Reporter: SINCE THE
CONNECTICUT SHOOTING, MORE THAN
100,000 AMERICANS HAVE SIGNED AN
ONLINE PETITION DEMANDING
PRESIDENT OBAMA PRODUCE
LEGISLATION LIMITING ACCESS TO
GUNS.
>> CASEY WIAN JOINS ME LIVE FROM
MESA, ARIZONA.
CASEY, JUST LISTENING TO THE GUN
SHOW CUSTOMERS IN YOUR PIECE,
THEY ALL SORT OF HAD SIMILAR
OPINIONS.
DID ANYONE IN YOUR CREW TALK TO
SAY THEY WERE OPEN TO ANY NEW
RESTRICTIONS?
AT ALL?
>> NONE OF THEM DID, BROOKE.
THEY TALKED ABOUT THE ISSUE OF
GUN SAFETY.
THEY SUPPORTED MORE CONTROLS ON
VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES.
THEY WERE VERY CONCERNED ABOUT
MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES.
BUT IN TERMS OF CHANGING GUN
LAWS, THE ONLY THING THERE WAS
SUPPORT FOR WAS LESS RESTRICTIVE
GUN LAWS.
SEVERAL PEOPLE TOLD US AT THE
GUN SHOW, AND HERE AT THIS
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN MESA,
ARIZONA, THAT THEY BELIEVE MORE
PEOPLE SHOULD BE ARMED AND
THAT'S THE WAY TO PREVENT MORE
LOSS OF LIFE AND TRAGEDIES LIKE
THIS ONE.
BROOKE?
>> CASEY WIAN FOR US IN ARIZONA.
CASEY, THANK YOU.
>>> UP NEXT, WE WANT TO SHARE
THIS KANSCAN CANDID AND VERY DI
CONVERSATION ABOUT HOW PARENTS
TALK TO ANDERSON COOPER ABOUT
HOW THEY TOLD THEIR CHILDREN
THAT THEIR TEACHER, MISS SOTO,
WAS NEVER COMING BACK TO SCHOOL.
BEGIN.
TOMATO,
OBVIOUSLY.
HAHA. THERE'S MORE
THAN THAT THOUGH,
THERE'S A KICK TO IT.
WAHLALALALALLALA!
SMOOTH, BUT CRISP.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE DRINKING
A FOOD THAT'S A DRINK,
OR A DRINK THAT'S A FOOD,
WOOOOOH!
[ Male Announcer ] TASTE IT
AND DESCRIBE THE INDESCRIBABLE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
>>> FOR SANDY HOOK PARENTS, THE
LOCATION OF THEIR CHILD'S
CLASSROOM MADE THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN LIFE AND DEATH.
THE MADDUXES ARE AMONG THE LUCKY
ONES.
THEIR SECOND-GRADER JORDAN WAS
IN A CLASSROOM JUST ACROSS THE
HALL FROM THE CLASS OF FIRST
GRADE TEACHER VICKI SOTO, WHO
DIED, SHIELDING HER LITTLE
STUDENTS.
AND JUST LAST NIGHT, HERE IN
NEWTOWN, ANDERSON COOPER SPOKE
WITH JORDAN'S PARENTS ABOUT HOW
THEY HAD TO TELL HER THAT HER
FAVORITE TEACHER, MISS SOTO, HAD
DIED.
>> THE FIRST TIME SHE TOLD US
THE STORY, SHE TOLD US ABOUT
HEARING THE GUNSHOTS, HER
CLASSROOM WAS RIGHT BEHIND THE
PRINCIPAL'S OFFICE AND THE
CONFERENCE ROOM THAT I
UNDERSTAND SOME OF THE FOLKS
WERE IN.
>> SHE WAS RIGHT ACROSS THE HALL
FROM VICTORIA SOTO'S CLASS.
>> RIGHT.
SOMETHING SHE WAS VERY EXCITED
ABOUT WHEN SHE LEARNED THAT SHE
WOULD BE GOING JUST ACROSS THE
HALL FROM HER FAVORITE TEACHER.
>> MISS SOTO WAS HER TEACHER
LAST YEAR?
>> YES.
THEY SPOKE, I THINK, ALMOST
DAILY.
AND THAT WAS THE HARDEST THING
TO HAVE TO TELL HER.
THAT'S WHEN SHE REALLY BROKE
DOWN.
SHE WAS HANDLING MOST OF IT
OKAY, TRYING TO PROCESS, BUT
WHEN WE TOLD HER ABOUT MISS
SOTO, THAT'S WHEN SHE TOOK IT
THE HARDEST.
>> SHE KNOWS THAT SHE'S --
>> YEAH, SHE KNOWS NOW.
>> WE WAITED.
WE WAITED UNTIL THE EVENTS OF
FRIDAY WERE OVER AND UNTIL
SATURDAY MORNING.
WE DIDN'T WANT HER TO FIND OUT
ANY OTHER WAY.
>> HOW DO YOU SAY THAT A
6-YEAR-OLD?
>> WE JUST EXPLAINED TO HER,
THAT, YOU KNOW, WE SAID, YOU
KNOW WHAT HAPPENED YESTERDAY,
AND HONESTLY SHE SAW ENOUGH TO
UNDERSTAND THAT THERE WERE
PEOPLE THAT DIDN'T WALK OUT OF
THERE.
>> SHE SAW SOMEBODY -- SHE SAW
SOMEBODY LAYING --
>> SHE SAW THE PRINCIPAL, YEAH.
SO THEY HAD TO WALK THE CHILDREN
OUT THROUGH THE FRONT DOOR WHERE
HER CLASSROOM WAS LOCATED, AND
SO SHE WALKED PAST A LOT.
WHILE THEY TOLD HEM TO CLOSE
THEIR EYES, I THINK SOME OF THEM
WERE PEEKING AS KIDS HAVE A
TENDENCY TO DO.
>> SHE SAW THE PRINCIPAL ON THE
FLOOR.
>> SHE SAW THE PRINCIPAL.
SHE SAW THE BLOOD.
SHE SAW -- SHE TOLD US ABOUT A
LOT OF BROKEN GLASS.
>> SO WHEN YOU ACTUALLY TOLD HER
THAT HER FORMER TEACHER HAD
DIED, HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN THAT?
>> UNFORTUNATELY IT'S VERY
SIMPLE.
YOU KNOW, WE CALMLY SAID,
JORDAN, SHE WAS ONE OF THE
TEACHERS WHO PASSED AWAY.
YOU KNOW, SHE HAD A MOMENT WHERE
SHE PAUSED AND HER EYES GOT REAL
WIDE AND SHE JUST -- YOU CAN
JUST SEE HER HEART SINK.
>> SHE LOOKED AT US AND SAID,
YOU KNOW, WHO AM I GOING TO TALK
TO EVERY DAY?
I SAID, THERE ARE OTHER TEACHERS
YOU'LL BE ABLE TO TALK TO.
BUT SHE SAID, YEAH, BUT SHE WAS
REALLY FUNNY.
>> WHAT WAS MISS SOTO LIKE?
I HEARD SO MANY GREAT THINGS
ABOUT HER AS A TEACHER.
>> SHE WAS JUST A REALLY KIND
INDIVIDUAL.
YOU CAN TELL THAT SHE HAD A
HEART FOR HER CHILDREN.
EACH AND EVERY ONE OF THEM.
AND SHE -- SHE MEANT BUSINESS,
WHICH WE LOVED.
>> SHE WAS YOUTHFUL.
OUR FIRST PARENT TEACHER
CONFERENCE, I FELT LIKE AN OLD
MAN.
WHO IS THIS -- SHE SEEMED BARELY
OUT OF HIGH SCHOOL HERSELF, BUT,
YOU KNOW, JUST A TESTAMENT TO
HER PERSONALITY AND HER NATURE.
>> RIGHT.
VERY MATURE.
SHE WAS A GREAT TEACHER.
SHE PUT EVERYTHING INTO WHAT SHE
DID.
THE KIDS ENJOYED LEARNING.
THERE WASN'T A DAY JORDAN SAID I
DON'T WANT TO GO TO SCHOOL.
>> VICKI SOTO, 27 YEARS OLD,
TEACHER OF FIRST GRADE.
A LOT OF PEOPLE AROUND HERE
CALLING HER A HERO.
ACCORDING TO OUR AFFILIATE WTNH,
THERE WERE 600 STUDENTS IN SANDY
HOOK ON FRIDAY MORNING.
>>> WE'LL TALK TO SOMEONE WHO
SAYS THE MOST DANGEROUS PERSON
IN SOCIETY IS SOMEONE HE CALLS A
GRIEVANCE COLLECTOR.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
APPARENTLY THIS YEAR THAT MEANS
IT IS PROVING TO BE ONE OF THE
WORST FOR MASS KILLINGS.
WE'LL ASK WHY.
QUESTIONS?
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
♪
BECOMING
PART OF THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
TREES WILL TALK TO NETWORKS
WILL TALK TO SCIENTISTS
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE.
CARS WILL TALK TO ROAD SENSORS
WILL TALK TO STOPLIGHTS
ABOUT TRAFFIC EFFICIENCY.
THE AMBULANCE WILL TALK
TO PATIENT RECORDS
WILL TALK TO DOCTORS
ABOUT SAVING LIVES.
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
THE NEXT BIG THING?
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
♪
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
♪
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
>>> BACK HERE LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
SINCE HE COMMITTED SUICIDE, IT
IS IMPOSSIBLE TO KNOW WHY THE
SHOOTER ACTED OUT, WHY.
HOWEVER, MOST OF US BELIEVE THE
ONLY LOGIC TO FOLLOW A PERSON
WHO GUNS DOWN PEOPLE, YOUNG
PEOPLE, 6, 7-YEAR-OLDS AT
RANDOM, MUST HAVE HAD SOME KIND
OF MENTAL ILLNESS.
BUT WHAT SPECIFICALLY COULD HAVE
MOTIVATED HIM HERE?
I WANT TO BRING IN ON THE PHONE
WITH ME NOW IS LARRY BARTON.
HE IS AN EXPERT IN THREAT
ASSESSMENT, MANAGING MORE THAN
2900 CASES OF THREATS AND
ASSAULTS AND MURDER.
LARRY, WELCOME.
I KNOW YOU'VE BEEN DOING THIS
FOR 28 YEARS.
AND NO TWO CASES ARE ALIKE.
WHEN YOU TALK TO PEOPLE AROUND
HERE, WE'RE TALKING
ITTY-BITTIES, 6 AND 7-YEAR-OLDS,
WILL WE EVER REALLY KNOW THE
ANSWER TO THE QUESTION WHY?
>> WHAT A GREAT QUESTION,
BROOKE.
I DON'T THINK SO.
I THINK IT WILL TAKE MONTHS IF
NOT YEARS TO EVEN GET HALF THE
STORY.
BUT THE MOST DANGEROUS PERSON IN
THE WORKPLACE AND IN SOCIETY IS
WHAT WE CALL THE GRIEVANCE
COLLECTOR, THE PERSON WHO IS
UPSET, MAYBE WITH WORK, WITH
POLICY, WITH CHILDREN, WITH --
THEY MAY HAVE MENTAL ILLNESS,
THEY MAY HAVE GRIEVANCES WITH
REGARDS TO FAMILY MEMBERS, AND
SO, NO, I THINK WE'LL NEVER HAVE
THE WHOLE STORY, BUT I CAN
GUARANTEE YOU THAT LAW
ENFORCEMENT OBVIOUSLY, THE
VICTIMS AND SO MANY WITNESSES
WILL HELP US PIECE TOGETHER.
BUT BETWEEN SOCIAL NETWORKING,
BEHAVIORAL SIGNS, AND SO MUCH
ELSE IN THE SHOOTER'S
BACKGROUND, IT WILL HELP US
UNDERSTAND NOT TO PREDICT
BECAUSE NO ONE IN SOCIETY CAN
PREDICT VIOLENCE.
IT IS IMPOSSIBLE.
THERE IS NO ONE AT THE FBI OR
THE AMERICAN COLLEGE, NO
SOFTWARE PROGRAM, BUT WE'RE
LEARNING MORE AND THESE HORRIBLE
TRAGEDIES DO HELP US UNDERSTAND
THE PERPETRATOR AND THE
GRIEVANCE A LITTLE BIT MORE
INTUITIVELY.
>> IN YOUR 28 YEARS, LARRY, HAVE
YOU EVER HEARD OF SOMEONE IN
THIS SENSELESS VIOLENCE, AGAINST
YOUNG PEOPLE.
YOUNG CHILDREN.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT THAT,
THE WHY PART?
>> THERE WAS A PENNSYLVANIA
SCHOOL THAT WAS ACTUALLY BLOWN
UP, YOU KNOW, FIVE DECADES AGO
BY A HORRIFIC PERSON.
SO IT IS NOT UNKNOWN IN SOCIETY,
BUT I WILL GIVE YOU MY BEST TAKE
AND IT WOULD BE THE FOLLOWING.
THAT WHEN A PERPETRATOR CROSSES
THE THRESHOLD, THEY NO LONGER
SEE PEOPLE AS HUMAN BEINGS.
RATHER THEY BECOME AN OBJECT.
THAT OBJECT MEANS THEY HAVE NO
EMPATHY, NO SYMPATHY, DON'T SEE
THEM AS A HUMAN BEING.
AND I'M NOT IN ANY WAY
JUSTIFYING ANY OF THIS.
I'M JUST SAYING IF HE WAS, FOR
INSTANCE, SCHIZOPHRENIC AND 1%
OF THE ENTIRE POPULATION OF THE
WORLD ACCORDING TO THE HOWARD
HUGHES INSTITUTE, HAS
SCHIZOPHRENIA.
IF HE WAS MENTALLY ILL, WHICH I
BELIEVE HE WAS, AND IF HE SAW
PEOPLE AS OBJECTS, IT DOES
SOMEHOW HELP US EXPLAIN HIS
MOTIVATION.
BUT OBVIOUSLY IN TERMS OF THE
WHY AND WHEN THAT DAY, WE MAY
LITERALLY NEVER KNOW.
>> LET ME ASK YOU THOUGH, LARRY,
IN TERMS OF THIS YEAR IN
GENERAL.
WE HAVE COVERED, I'M SICK OF
COVERING THESE MASS MURDERS AND
THIS YEAR, THIS YEAR, 2012,
REALLY GOES DOWN AS THE WORST IN
A DECADE.
WHY IS THAT?
>> WELL, I BELIEVE -- UP UNTIL
THIS YEAR I WAS NOT CONVINCED
ISSUES SUCH AS THE ECONOMY WERE
PLAYING A ROLE, BUT I THINK WHAT
IS HAPPENING IS PEOPLE ARE
FALLING OUT OF MEDICAL SYSTEMS,
NOT BEING REIMBURSED FOR MEDICAL
CARE.
SOMETIMES THE DROP IN SOCIETY
MEANS PEOPLE ARE NOT GETTING THE
MEDICATIONS, UNABLE TO SEE THEIR
PHYSICIANS.
THAT'S A VERY SERIOUS ISSUE.
THE OTHER IS CLEARLY THE WHOLE
PROBLEM OF COPYCATS.
IF YOU LOOK AT THIS YEAR, WHICH
IS AS YOU SAID WILL BE THE
WORST, THE SIKH TEMPLE SHOOTING
OR FT. HOOD OR NEW YORK CITY, WE
HAVE TO NOT BLAME YOUNG PEOPLE
THERE IS A LOT OF CHATTER BY
SO-CALLED EXPERTS THAT SAY THIS
IS MOSTLY DONE BY YOUNG PEOPLE.
MANY OF THESE PERPETRATORS ARE
IN THEIR 30s, 40s AND 50s.
SO IN TERMS OF WHY, I THINK PART
OF IT IS MENTAL HEALTH GAPS.
BUT, TWO, WE HAVE TO BE CART TO
UNDERSTAND, YOU WERE BORN WITH
INTUITION.
YOUR MOM AND DAD GAVE YOU THAT
GIFT AT BIRTH.
AND IF YOU SEE OR SENSE SOMEONE
THAT YOU LOVE OR SOMEONE THAT
YOU WORK WITH OR IT MAY BE A
NEIGHBOR, WHO IS STRUGGLING WITH
ISSUES, OR IS JUST LITERALLY
BEYOND BIZARRE, POLICE WILL DO A
WELLNESS CHECK.
THEY'LL KNOCK ON THE DOOR OF
THAT PERSON.
THEY'LL TRY TO TALK WITH THEM TO
FIND OUT WHAT IS GOING ON AND DO
SOME SOFT OBSERVATION.
THAT'S WHY WE HAVE SO MANY
WONDERFUL EXPERTS IN OUR OWN
COMMUNITY.
AND IN THIS CASE WE JUST NEED
MORE PEOPLE TO SPEAK UP.
>> LARRY BARTON, THANK YOU FOR
YOUR PERSPECTIVE.
>> THANK YOU, BROOKE.
>> BACK IN JUST A MOMENT.
[ Male Announcer ]
RESEARCH SUGGESTS CELL HEALTH
PLAYS A KEY ROLE
THROUGHOUT OUR LIVES.
One A Day Men's 50+
IS A COMPLETE MULTIVITAMIN
DESIGNED FOR MEN'S HEALTH
CONCERNS AS WE AGE.
IT HAS 7 ANTIOXIDANTS
TO SUPPORT CELL HEALTH.
One A Day Men's 50+.
(Announcer) When Subaru owners
Tlook in the mirror,TH.
they see more than themselves.
So we celebrate our year-end
with the "share the love" event.
Get a great deal on a new Subaru
and 250 dollars goes to your
choice of five charities.
By the end of this, our fifth
year,
our total can reach almost 25
million dollars.
It's a nice reflection on us
all.
Now through January 2nd.
>>> WE WANT TO RETURN QUICKLY
NOW TO THE BIG STORY OUT OF
WASHINGTON.
THERE HAS BEEN ANOTHER MEETING
AT THE WHITE HOUSE TODAY BETWEEN
THE PRESIDENT AND HOUSE SPEAKER
JOHN BOEHNER.
A SIGN, PERHAPS, OF SOME
CONCRETE PROGRESS TOWARD
AVERTING THE SO-CALLED FISCAL
CLIFF.
THAT LOOMING EVENT THAT WOULD
BRING HIGHER TAXES FOR EVERYONE
AND BLUNT FORCE GOVERNMENT
SPENDING CUTS, INCLUDING CUTS TO
THE PENTAGON BUDGET, COME
JANUARY 1st.
DANA BASH IS ON CAPITOL HILL.
WE HAVE TWO WEEKS NOW TO GO
UNTIL THE DEADLINE.
BUT THERE WAS THIS 45-MINUTE
MEETING AT THE WHITE HOUSE
TODAY.
WHAT'S IT ALL MEAN?
>> Reporter: YOU KNOW, I WISH I
WAS A FLY ON THE WALL.
I'M SURE YOU DO TOO, IN THAT
MEETING.
THE FACT THAT IT WAS 45 MINUTES,
YOU KNOW, IT MAKES YOU A LITTLE
BIT CONCERNED THAT MAYBE IF IT
WERE LONGER THEY WOULD HAVE MORE
PROGRESS.
BUT THE FACT OF THE MATTER IS
OVER THE PAST FOUR, FIVE DAYS OR
SO, ACCORDING TO SOURCES IN BOTH
PARTIES, THERE HAS BEEN GENERAL
PROGRESS MADE.
AND DIEDRA WALSH AND I HAVE BEEN
HEARING FROM SOURCES, BOTH
PARTIES, THAT RIGHT NOW AT THIS
POINT THE TALKS ARE CENTERED
AROUND ABOUT A $2 TRILLION DEAL,
A TRILLION DOLLARS IN SPENDING
CUTS, ABOUT A TRILLION DOLLARS
IN TAX REVENUE.
WE SHOULD EMPHASIZE THIS IS WHAT
THE REPUBLICANS ARE PUSHING.
DEMOCRATIC SOURCES SAY THEY'RE
STILL NOT SURE BIG PICTURE, THAT
THEY COULD PASS THIS, BECAUSE
MUCH OF THE SPENDING HAD TO DO
WITH CHANGES IN MEDICARE THAT
MIGHT BE HARD FOR DEMOCRATS TO
SWALLOW.
ALL OF THE SPECIFICS ABOUT RATE
CUTS AND THINGS THAT REALLY
DIVIDE THEM ARE STILL WAITING TO
HEAR, BUT THE FACT THEY'RE
TALKING IS DEFINITELY A GOOD
SIGN.
GIVEN WHERE WE ARE ON THE
CALENDAR.
>> THE DIFFERENCE IS VERY MUCH
STILL THERE, BUT APPARENTLY
NARROWING WITH SPEAKER BOEHNER
NOW AT LEAST AGREEING THAT THERE
COULD BE SOME ACTUAL HIKES IN
THE TAX RATES.
>> EXACTLY.
EXACTLY.
THAT SEEMED TO BE WHAT KIND OF
OPENED UP THIS PROGRESS THAT
WE'RE TOLD ABOUT FROM BOTH
SIDES, THE FACT THAT REPUBLICANS
COULD GO FOR THAT.
NOW, WHAT HE PROPOSED WAS
RAISING TAX RATES FOR PEOPLE
WITH AN INCOME OF A MILLION
DOLLARS OR MORE.
DEMOCRATS AND THE PRESIDENT
CAMPAIGNED CONSTANTLY ON THE
IDEA OF RAISING TAX RATES FOR
FAMILIES MAKING $250,000 OR
MORE.
THAT'S A NONSTARTER FOR THE
WHITE HOUSE.
THE IDEA OF PUTTING HIGHER TAX
RATES FOR WEALTHY AMERICANS OF
ANY SORT TO THE TABLE WAS
CONSIDERED A BREAKTHROUGH.
>> DANA, THE HORRIFIC EVENTS IN
NEWTOWN IN A WAY CAST A SHADOW
OVER THE ENTIRE COUNTRY.
WASHINGTON ALSO.
WE SAW A MOMENT OF SILENCE AT
THE SENATE.
JUST A FEW MINUTES AGO.
WHAT ABOUT ACTION?
WHAT ARE SENATORS SAYING ABOUT
ACTUAL ACTION ON THE HILL?
>> Reporter: WELL, YOU KNOW
THIS, JOHN, YOU'VE BEEN COVERING
POLITICS FOR YEARS AS WELL, THAT
PART OF THE -- REALLY THE MAIN
REASON WE HAVE NOT SEEN ANY
ACTION ON GUN CONTROL IS BECAUSE
DEMOCRATS PULLED BACK BIG TIME
FROM PUSHING THIS ISSUE BECAUSE
THEY REALLY GOT CRUSHED
POLITICALLY, RED STATES, FROM
THE PRESIDENTIAL LEVEL, ON DOWN.
SO THEY JUST THOUGHT IT WAS BAD
POLITICS.
BUT IT DOES SEEM THAT THIS TIME,
BECAUSE OF THE NATURE OF THIS
SHOOTING, BECAUSE WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT SMALL CHILDREN, THERE IS A
DIFFERENT FEELING, A DIFFERENT
ATMOSPHERE HERE.
JOE MANCHIN, DEMOCRATIC SENATOR
WHO IS AN -- HE SAID HE THINKS
THERE SHOULD BE STRICTER GUN
LAWS.
WHY DO YOU THINK THIS MOMENT MAY
BE DIFFERENT?
>> BECAUSE I THINK IT IS A
LOGICAL CONTINUUM.
IF THERE SHOULD BE A SAFE PLACE
IN AMERICA, IT IS AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
AND HERE IN THIS ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, LOOK WHAT HAPPENED.
6-YEAR-OLDS WITH 3 TO 11 BULLETS
FROM THIS BUSHMASTER IN THEIR
BODY, 20 OF THEM.
IS THIS AMERICA?
I DON'T THINK SO.
AND I THINK THESE INCIDENTS ARE
GOING TO CONTINUE UNTIL WE DO
SOMETHING TO CHANGE THE SUPPLY
MODE OF THESE WEAPONS OUT IN OUR
SOCIETY.
>> Reporter: AND, JOHN, WHEN I
TALKED TO SENATOR FEINSTEIN, SHE
JUST HUNG UP THE PHONE WITH HER
DEMOCRATIC COLLEAGUE FROM WEST
VIRGINIA, JOE MANCHIN.
THE TWO DECIDED THEY WOULD COME
TOGETHER AND TALK TO SENATOR
MANCHIN ABOUT WAYS SHE MIGHT BE
ABLE TO CHANGE HER LEGISLATION
TO GET HIM ON BOARD.
THAT WOULD BE FROM HER
PERSPECTIVE A BIG, BIG DEAL TO
HELP PUSH ALONG THIS LEGISLATION
THAT STILL HAS A LONG WAY TO GO.
A LOT OF POLITICS TO OVERCOME.
>> THAT WOULD BE A BIG DEAL, TO
PUSH SOME KIND OF BOTH SIDE OF
THE DEMOCRATIC PARTY.
DANA BASH FROM CAPITOL HILL,
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>>> WHEN WE COME BACK, BROOKE
BALDWIN WILL HAVE MORE ON THE
TRAGEDY FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
looked away from my screen.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
That kind of focus...
that's what I have
when I trade.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
And the StreetSmart Edge trading
platform from Charles Schwab...
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
...helps me keep an eye on
what's really important to me.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
It's packed with tools that
help me work my strategies,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
spot patterns and find
opportunities more easily.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Then, when I'm ready...
act decisively.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
I can even access it from the
cloud and trade on any computer.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
With the exact same tools,
the exact same way.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
And the reality is,
with Schwab Mobile,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
I can focus on trading
anyplace, anytime...
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
...until I choose to focus
on something else.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Trade at Schwab for
$8.95 a trade.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Open an account and trade
up to 6 months commission-free
online equity trading
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
with a $50,000 deposit.
Call 1-800-786-7803
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
and a Trading Specialist
will help you get started today.
>>> TOP OF THE HOUR HERE LIVE ON
CNN.
I'M BROOKE BALDWIN IN A VERY
GRAY AND RAINY AND COLD NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WHERE, TODAY, THE
NEW REALITY IS SETTING IN.
TODAY, PARENTS ARE LIVING
ALONGSIDE AN EMPTY ROOM OF A
CHILD THEY LOST, LEFT BEHIND IN
THAT ROOM, PAJAMAS, FAVORITE
TOYS, BOOKS THEY HAD ALWAYS READ
TOGETHER, EVEN THE SMELL OF
THEIR CHILD'S PILLOW.
LET'S NOT FORGET THE FIRST
RESPONDERS HERE.
THEY'RE BEING CALLED HEROES.
BUT THEY ARE STILL LIVING WITH
THE IMAGES NO ONE COULD HAVE
PREPARED THEM TO SEE.
TODAY, FAMILIES ARE DECIDING ON
COFFINS, DECIDING ON HEADSTONES,
CHOOSING SONGS THAT WILL PLAY AT
THE FUNERALS OF FIRST GRADERS.
LET ME TELL YOU ABOUT TWO LITTLE
BOYS HERE, THESE TWO LITTLE BOYS
ARE BEING REMEMBERED RIGHT NOW
IN NEWTOWN.
THE FUNERAL FOR 6-YEAR-OLD JACK
PINTO STARTED JUST A COUPLE OF
HOURS AGO.
JACK WILL BE LAID TO REST TODAY
IN NEWTOWN VILLAGE CEMETERY.
A MOURNER AT JACK'S FUNERAL SAYS
PEOPLE SANG MANY HYMNS, THE
SERVICE EMPHASIZED A SPECIAL
MESSAGE FOR CHILDREN AND
REASSURING THEM YOU'RE SECURE
NOW, THE WORST IS OVER.
WE'RE TOLD LITTLE JACK ADORED
FOOTBALL.
HIS FAVORITE PLAYER WAS NEW YORK
GIANTS RECEIVER VICTOR CRUZ.
HE WATCHES GIANTS GAMES WHILE
PROUDLY WEARING CRUZ'S JERSEY.
LOOK AT THAT CUTE CHEEK.
CRUZ PAID TRIBUTE TO HIS YOUNG
FAN BY SCRIBBLING JACK PINTO, MY
HERO, ON ONE CLEAT AND R.I.P.
JACK PINTO ON THE OTHER.
ON HIS GLOVES, HE WROTE, JACK
PINTO THIS ONE IS FOR YOU.
>> IT WAS EMOTIONAL.
I WAS FIGHTING BACK TEARS A
LITTLE BIT TO DO IT.
AND IT FELT, YOU KNOW, IT FELT
GOOD.
IT FELT GOOD TO HONOR A FAMILY
GOING THROUGH SO MUCH.
THEY SEEM LOOK A STRONG FAMILY.
I SPOKE TO THE OLDER BROTHER,
AND, HE WAS DISTRAUGHT AS WELL.
HE WAS -- HE COULDN'T SAY MUCH,
JUST HOW HIS BROTHER WAS, HOW I
WAS HIS BROTHER'S FAVORITE
PLAYER.
AND HE WAS, YOU KNOW, HE WAS
FIGHTING TEARS.
HE COULD BARELY SPEAK TO ME.
>> ALSO WANT TO TELL YOU ABOUT
6-YEAR-OLD NOAH POZNER.
HIS FUNERAL STARTED A COUPLE OF
HOURS AGO IN NEARBY MONROE,
CONNECTICUT.
HIS AUNT SAYS NOAH SOMETIMES
BATTED HIS LONG EYELASHES.
HE TRIED TO GET WHAT HE WANTED
WITH HIS EYELASHES AND HE LIT UP
EVERYONE'S HEART.
>> NOAH WAS EXTREMELY LIVELY.
HE WAS REALLY THE LIGHT OF THE
ROOM, YOU KNOW.
HE HAD A HUGE HEART, AND HE WAS
SO MUCH FUN.
A LITTLE BIT RAMBUNCTIOUS, LOTS
OF SPIRIT.
HE LOVED PLAYING WITH ALL OF HIS
COUSINS.
HE LOVED HIS TWIN THE MOST OF
ALL, AND ALWAYS SAID HE WAS, YOU
KNOW, THEY WERE BEST FRIENDS.
>> NOAH'S TWIN SISTER ARIEL
ATTENDED SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AS WELL.
BUT YOU SEE WITH HER STORY, SHE
WAS ASSIGNED TO A DIFFERENT
CLASSROOM THAN HER BROTHER.
ARIEL ESCAPED THE SHOOTING ALONG
WITH THEIR 8-YEAR-OLD SISTER,
SOPHIA.
OUTSIDE OF NOAH'S FUNERAL, WELL
WISHERS PUT TWO TEDDY BEARS, A
BOUQUET OF WHITE FLOWERS AND A
SINGLE RED ROSE UNDERNEATH AN
OLD MAPLE TREE.
>>> POLICE IN CONNECTICUT ARE
PIECING TOGETHER CLUES TRYING TO
FIND OUT WHY, WHY FRIDAY'S
SHOOTING HAPPENED.
A LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIAL SAYS
SMASHED UP COMPUTERS WERE FOUND
AND GRABBED FROM THE HOME WHERE
THE GUNMAN LIVED.
INVESTIGATORS NOW GATHERED UP
ALL THE BROKEN PARTS TO EXAMINE
THEM.
CNN IS ALSO LEARNING THAT THE
SHOOTER'S MOTHER HERE, HER NAME
WAS NANCY LANZA, SHE WAS
PLANNING TO MOVE.
A CLOSE FRIEND OF HERS SAYS
LANZA HAD TOLD HER, QUOTE, THIS
WOULD BE HER LAST WINTER IN HER
CURRENT HOME.
AND AS WE CONTINUE THE
CONVERSATION, TALKING ABOUT HOW
THESE FAMILIES HERE IN NEWTOWN
ARE COPING, I JUST WANT TO ALSO
TALK ABOUT THE OTHER FOLKS WHO
ARE STRUGGLING NOW.
THE FIRST RESPONDERS.
THEY WERE ON THE SCENE.
THEY MET THESE GRIEVING PARENTS
IN THOSE MOMENTS OF CONFUSION
AND SHOCK.
JUST A SHORT TIME AGO, AFTER I
NOTICED SOME WREATHS, SOME 26
WREATHS BEING DELIVERED HERE, IN
TOWN, ONE FIREFIGHTER STOPPED
AND SPOKE WITH ME.
>> HOW MANY WREATHS ARE THERE?
>> 26.
>> 26 WREATHS.
SO WHERE DID THEY GET SENT TO
THE FIREHOUSE?
>> THEY WERE SENT TO THE
FIREHOUSE THROUGH U.P.S.
>> DID YOU KNOW THEY WERE
COMING?
>> NO.
NO, THEY WERE -- THE TRUCK
PULLED UP AND SHE SAYS I HAVE A
DELIVERY OF 26 WREATHS.
WE UNLOADED THEM ALL.
WE FIGURED WE WOULD COME UP WITH
A PLACE TO PUT THEM.
TRY TO KEEP THEM ALL TOGETHER
AND SHIPPED ALL THE WAY FROM
OREGON.
>> HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN HERE?
>> SINCE FRIDAY.
>> WHERE ARE YOU BASED OUT OF?
>> THE SANDY HOOK FIREHOUSE?
>> HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN AT THE
FIREHOUSE?
>> WELL, WE'RE GOING HOME
TONIGHT TO SLEEP.
>> YEARS.
>> YEARS, SINCE HIGH SCHOOL, I'M
38.
>> SINCE HIGH SCHOOL.
YOU'RE 38.
>> YEAH.
>> DID YOU EVER IN A MILLION
YEARS THINK YOU WOULD BE
EXPERIENCING THIS IN YOUR LITTLE
TOWN?
>> NOBODY IN THIS TOWN EVER
WOULD THINK THAT, YEAH.
>> WHERE WERE YOU WHEN YOU
HEARD?
>> WORKING.
I WORK ACROSS TOWN.
WE SAW THE HELICOPTERS.
>> WHEN YOU SAW THE HELICOPTERS,
WHAT DID YOU THINK IT WAS?
>> NOT ON THE SCALE IT WAS.
ONE OR TWO.
WE HEARD THE PRINCIPAL AT FIRST,
AND -- AS TIME WENT ON, WE GOT
THE REPORTS.
JUST DIDN'T BELIEVE IT.
WE CAME DOWN THE ROAD.
IT WAS JUST ALL SURREAL.
SEEING ALL THE CARS.
ALL THIS.
TOUGH.
>> WHERE DID YOU GO ONCE YOU SAW
THE CARS?
STRAIGHT TO THE FIREHOUSE?
>> STRAIGHT TO THE FIREHOUSE.
FROM THERE WE JUST --
>> HELP US AROUND THE WORLD
UNDERSTAND WHAT YOU AS A FIRST
RESPONDER ARE GOING THROUGH.
>> SADNESS, ANGER, GUILT IN SOME
ASPECTS.
>> WHY GUILT?
WHAT COULD YOU HAVE DONE?
>> EXACTLY.
I MEAN, WE'RE HAVING COUNSELING.
AS A GROUP.
>> CAN I GET YOUR FIRST AND LAST
NAME?
>> NAME'S JEFFREY THOMAS.
>> JEFFREY THOMAS.
SINCE HIGH SCHOOL.
>> SINCE HIGH SCHOOL.
>> FINALLY, WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF
THE WREATHS, JUST PEOPLE YOU
DON'T KNOW, SENDING YOU ALL
THESE WREATHS TO PUT UP IN YOUR
TOWN?
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY TO THE PEOPLE
OF PORTLAND, OREGON?
>> THANK YOU.
IT MAKES US FEEL WARM TO KNOW
THIS IS -- IT IS AMAZING THAT
PEOPLE THAT FAR AWAY CARE ABOUT
US.
>> SO MANY PEOPLE I KNOW CARE
ABOUT THESE PEOPLE AND THE TOWN
OF NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
SO MANY ISSUES THAT PEOPLE ARE
WORKING THROUGH, IN THE
AFTERMATH OF THIS TRAGEDY.
I WANT TO BRING IN PSYCHOLOGIST
WENDY WALSH WHO JOINS ME FROM
LOS ANGELES.
I WANT TO BEGIN WITH A POINT
THAT THAT YOUNG FIREFIGHTER
BROUGHT UP WITH ME, IT BROKE MY
HEART TO HEAR HIM SAY GUILT.
GUILT AS ONE OF THE EMOTIONS
HE'S SORT OF COPING WITH.
HOW DO THEY SORT THROUGH THESE
EMOTIONS IN THE DAYS AFTER THE
SHOOTING?
>> IT IS IMPORTANT TO REMEMBER
THAT SURVIVOR'S GUILT CAN HIT
ANYBODY.
IT IS REALLY COMMON, BROOKE, IN
FIRST RESPONDERS, BUT IT IS EVEN
COMMON IN ALL OF US.
YOU KNOW, WHEN I ASK PEOPLE HOW
ARE YOU FEELING?
EVEN MY FRIENDS AND COLLEAGUES
AT CNN WHEN I SAY HOW IS IT
GOING?
THEY SAY, WELL, IT'S TERRIBLE,
BUT NOT AS BAD AS THOSE PARENTS,
LIKE SOMEHOW IT IS NOT OKAY FOR
US TO FEEL AS SAD AS THOSE
PARENTS WHO FELT THE LOSS.
OBVIOUSLY THEIR LOSS IS MORE
REAL, IT WILL LAST A LONGER
TIME, BUT THIS COMMUNITY
GRIEVING, WE SHOULD ALL GIVE
OURSELVES TIME FOR.
IT IS REALLY IMPORTANT THAT WE
ALLOW OURSELVES TIME TO GRIEVE
BECAUSE THAT'S WHERE THE HEALING
WORK IS DONE.
>> YEAH, YOU TALK ABOUT
SURVIVOR'S GUILT.
WE HEAR THE STORIES OF PEOPLE IN
NEWTOWN WHOSE CHILDREN WERE IN
CLASSES ACROSS THE WALL OR
LITTLE ONE PLAYED DEAD AMIDST
THE YOUNG FOLKS WHO DIDN'T MAKE
IT.
AND THAT PERSON SURVIVED AND
THESE PARENTS WALKING AROUND
SORT OF WITH HEAVY HEARTS.
THEY FEEL GUILTY AS WELL.
BUT ALSO JUST, WENDY, I KNOW
PEOPLE ALL AROUND THE WORLD, YOU
KNOW, I HAVE FAMILY MEMBERS,
PEOPLE HAVE FAMILY MEMBERS, THEY
HAVEN'T HAD A DRY EYE IN DAYS.
HOW DO YOU ADVISE THEM AS THEY
MOVE FORWARD?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, WE ALL DEAL
WITH THIS KIND OF EMOTIONAL
TRAUMA IN DIFFERENT WAYS.
SOME PEOPLE NEED TO BE ACTIVE.
THE EXTRA VE
OTHERS NEED TO DISTRACT
THEMSELVES AND SAYING WHY ARE
THEY BEING SO OBLIVIOUS, DON'T
THEY KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON AND
BUSY THEMSELVES WITH OTHER
THINGS.
THAT'S WHY AROUND FUNERALS,
THERE IS A LOT OF FOOD
PREPARATION AND BRINGING OF FOOD
BECAUSE IT GIVES YOU SOMETHING
TO DO.
STILL, OTHER PEOPLE WILL BE NUMB
FOR A WHILE UNTIL A TIDAL WAVE
OF SADNESS MAY SHOW UP.
OTHER PEOPLE MAY JUST FEEL
IRRITABLE AND ANGRY AND NOT KNOW
WHY.
YOU SEE THOSE PEOPLE COMING OUT
IN GIANT DEBATE OVER GUN
CONTROL.
EITHER SIDE OF THE ISSUE,
THEY'RE QUITE ANGRY RIGHT NOW.
SO THESE ARE ALL SYMPTOMS OF THE
TRAUMA.
AND IT IS IMPORTANT TO JUST SORT
OF ALLOW OURSELVES TO HAVE IT
FOR A TIME, BUT IT IS ALSO
REALLY IMPORTANT TO NOT ACT,
THINK OR TALK OUT OF A PLACE
FROM FEAR, A PLACE OF FEAR.
IT IS IMPORTANT THAT WE ALLOW
OUR BEHAVIORS TO BE GOVERNED BY
LOVE.
AND GOOD ACTS.
AND LIKE THE WREATHS YOU SHOWED
THAT WERE BLIZZARDE EDELIVERED
THE FIREFIGHTERS AND THE PEOPLE
IN PORTLAND, TOO.
>> I ALWAYS SAY IT IS THE LITTLE
THINGS AND IT WAS PRETTY AMAZING
WATCHING THE FIREFIGHTERS SORT
OF HANGING THESE WREATHS AROUND
TOWN AND THEY KNEW SOMEONE, ALL
THE WAY ACROSS THE COUNTRY,
CARED ENOUGH ABOUT THEM AND YOU
CAN JUST TELL IT MEANT THE WORLD
TO THEM.
I WANT TO ASK YOU ABOUT
SOMETHING ELSE.
THERE WAS A PRETTY STUNNING
PIECE, FROM THE BLUE REVIEW,
PUBLISHED TODAY IN THE
HUFFINGTON POST, WRITTEN BY A
MOTHER, TITLED I AM ADAM LANZA'S
MOTHER, THE SHOOTER HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
HER NAME IS LIZA LONG.
SHE TALKS ABOUT HER BRIGHT BUT
TROUBLED 13-YEAR-OLD SON WHO AT
TIMES HAS PULLED A KNIFE ON HER,
THREATENED TO KILL HER,
THREATENED TO KILL HIMSELF.
I WANT TO QUOTE HER HERE.
SHE WROTE, NO ONE WANTS TO SEND
A 13-YEAR-OLD GENIUS WHO LOVES
HARRY POTTER AND HIS SNUGGLE
ANIMAL COLLECTION TO JAIL.
BUT OUR SOCIETY WITH ITS STIGMA
ON MENTAL ILLNESS AND ITS BROKEN
HEALTH CARE SYSTEM DOES NOT
PROVIDE US WITH OTHER OPTIONS.
THEN ANOTHER TORTURED SOUL
SHOOTS UP A FAST FOOD
RESTAURANT.
A MALL.
A KINDERGARTEN CLASSROOM.
AND WE WRITTEN OUR HANDS AND SAY
SOMETHING MUST BE DONE.
HOW DO YOU RESPOND TO THAT?
>> YOU KNOW, SHE'S DEAD ON.
AS THE CONVERSATION HAS BEEN
ABOUT GUN CONTROL, AND THAT'S A
VERY VALID CONVERSATION TO BE
HAVING IN THESE TIMES, I THINK
THE CONVERSATION ABOUT MENTAL
HEALTH REFORM IS EQUALLY
IMPORTANT HERE.
PARENTS, I THINK ABOUT THE
ARIZONA SHOOTER, YOU KNOW, WHO
WAS EXHIBITING EARLY SIGNS OF
SCHIZOPHRENIA, HE WAS OVER THE
AGE OF 18, ONCE YOU'RE OVER THE
AGE OF 18, NOBODY CAN MAKE YOU
GO TO A PSYCHIATRIST.
NOBODY CAN MAKE YOU TAKE YOUR
MEDS.
PARENTS LOVE THEIR CHILD, SO THE
BEST THING THEY CAN DO IS GIVE A
ROOF OVER HIS HEAD AND FOOD.
AND I THINK THAT THAT'S THE
IMPORTANT THING IS THAT WE --
WE'RE SO FOCUSED ON INDIVIDUAL
RIGHTS AND FREEDOMS AND OF
COURSE DENYING SOMEONE THEIR
FREEDOM IS A BAD THING AND
HISTORICALLY WE HAD ATROCITIES
HAPPEN WITH LOCKING PEOPLE UP
BECAUSE THEY HAD STRANGE
POLITICAL BELIEFS LIKE MAYBE
WOMEN SHOULD HAVE TO VOTE OR
SOMETHING IN THE '20s.
WE HAVE TO GIVE TOOLS AND ACCESS
TO PARENTS OF MENTALLY ILL
CHILDREN.
OR MENTALLY ILL YOUNG ADULTS
MORE IMPORTANTLY.
BECAUSE OUR ONLY OPTION IS AS
PARENTS IS TO KEEP THEM AND FEED
THEM AND DEAL WITH WHAT THEY'RE
DEALING WITH, OR TO PUT THEM ON
THE STREET AS HOMELESS, BROOKE,
I'VE HEARD AS MUCH AS ONE-THIRD
OF OUR PRISON POPULATION ARE
ACTUALLY SUFFER FROM MENTAL
ILLNESS AND ARE NOT GETTING THE
HELP THEY NEED.
>> THAT IS PRECISELY ONE OF HER
POINTS.
SHE WAS TALKING ABOUT, WHAT DO I
DO?
MY CHILD HAS TO BE CHARGED WITH
A CRIMINAL ACT FOR HIM OR HER TO
GO TO JAIL.
THERE SHOULD BE ANOTHER OPTION.
THERE SHOULD BE ANOTHER OPTION
AND THE CONVERSATION NEEDS TO BE
HAD IN TERMS OF MENTAL ILLNESS
IN THIS COUNTRY.
WE'RE HAVING IT TODAY.
IT WILL CONTINUE.
WENDY WALSH, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
SOMETHING TO BE THINKING ABOUT
HERE AS WE MOVE FORWARD.
>>> FOR MORE INFORMATION, I KNOW
A LOT OF YOU ARE REACHING OUT,
ASKING HOW YOU CAN HELP THOSE
AFFECTED HERE IN NEWTOWN.
GO TO CNN.COM/IMPACT.
CNN.COM/IMPACT AND THERE ARE
MULTIPLE WAYS WHERE YOU CAN
HELP, YOU CAN GIVE, ET CETERA.
>>> COMING UP, WE'LL TAKE YOU
INTO THE STREETS OF NEWTOWN
INCLUDING THE FIREHOUSE.
THE FIREHOUSE WHERE ALL THOSE
PARENTS FIRST HEARD THE NEWS
FRIDAY MORNING AND WE'LL SHOW
YOU THE FUNERAL HOME.
ABSOLUTELY OVERWHELMED RIGHT
NOW.
PLUS, WE SHOULD TELL YOU, TAKE A
LOOK AT THIS LIVE PICTURE, THE
GOVERNOR HERE OF THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT, DAN MALLOY, HE WILL
BE HOLDING A NEWS CONFERENCE AT
THE BOTTOM OF THE HOUR AS SOON
AS WE SEE THE GOVERNOR, WE WILL
BRING THAT TO YOU LIVE.
LIVE SPECIAL HERE FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
[ Male Announcer ]
RED LOBSTER'S CRABFEST
ENDS SOON.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OUR TENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
♪ HARK HOW THE BELLS,
SWEET SILVER BELLS ♪
♪ ALL SEEM TO SAY
THROW CARE AWAY ♪
♪ FROM EVERYWHERE,
FILLING THE AIR ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
CHEX PARTY MIX.
EASY 15-MINUTE
HOMEMADE RECIPES
YOU JUST POP IN A MICROWAVE.
LIKE CARAMEL CHOCOLATE
DRIZZLES.
HAPPIER HOLIDAYS.
CHEX PARTY MIX.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN DIARRHEA HITS,
KAOPECTATE STOPS IT FAST.
POWERFUL LIQUID RELIEF
SPEEDS TO THE SOURCE.
FAST.
[ Male Announcer ]
STOP THE UH-OH FAST
WITH KAOPECTATE.
>>> TEACHERS ARE OFTENTIMES
HAILED AS HEROES, BUT FRIDAY THE
TEACHERS OF SANDY HOOK LIVED UP
TO THE WORD IN A WAY NO TEACHER
EVER SHOULD HAVE TO.
LAST NIGHT, ANDERSON COOPER HERE
IN NEWTOWN SPOKE WITH JANET
VOLLMER WHO READ TO HER CLASS OF
5-YEAR-OLD CHILDREN AS THIS
MASSACRE WAS TAKING PLACE
SOMEWHERE BEYOND HER CLASSROOM
DOOR.
THEY WERE AT SANDY HOOK.
A MONTH OR SO AGO HER CLASS HAD
JUST PRACTICED AN EMERGENCY
DRILL AND THEN FRIDAY SHE HEARD
THE LOUDSPEAKER, SHE HEARD THESE
NOISES, AND SHE KNEW THINGS WERE
NOT RIGHT.
>> SO THERE WERE NOISES THAT
DIDN'T SOUND CORRECT.
SO THERE WAS NO -- ANYONE
TELLING US THAT IT WAS A DRILL,
WE JUST THOUGHT SOMETHING WAS
NOT RIGHT.
WE SAT IN THE CUBBY AREA AWAY
FROM THE DOOR SO NO ONE COULD
SEE US AND READ THEM A STORY,
TALKED TO THEM, YOU KNOW, THEY
KEPT SAYING HOW COME WE'RE HERE
FOR SO LONG?
I SAID, WELL, IT WILL BE A
LITTLE LONGER.
THEY'RE 5, YOU TELL THEM
WHATEVER YOU DO TO KEEP THEM
SAFE AND KEEP THEM CALM.
>> THIS IS WHAT I'VE BEEN
THINKING ABOUT ALL WEEKEND,
THOUGH.
THE COURAGE FOR YOU TO BE ABLE
TO SIT THERE AND READ A STORY,
AND KEEP THEM CALM --
>> I THINK THE ADRENALINE KICKS
IN AND YOU DO WHAT YOU HAVE TO
DO.
THERE WAS TWO OTHER PEOPLE IN
THE ROOM HELPING ME WITH, YOU
KNOW, PULLING DOWN THE BLINDS
AND THAT.
I WAS FOCUSED ON THE KIDS AND
KEEPING THEM SAFE.
I'M NOT ABOUT TO TELL THEM I
THINK SOMETHING IS VERY BAD OR
VERY WRONG.
WE WAITED AND WAITED.
AND IT SEEMED LIKE A VERY LONG
TIME, AND MAYBE IT WAS 20
MINUTES, HALF AN HOUR, I'LL NOT
SURE.
THERE WERE KNOCKS AT THE DOOR.
IT WAS POLICE, SOMEONE, TELLING
US WE HAD TO LEAVE.
DIDN'T WANT TO OPEN THE DOOR AT
FIRST.
BUT WE DID.
AND THEY SAID, HAVE THE CHILDREN
WALK, HOLD HANDS, COVER THEIR
EYES IF THEY COULD, BECAUSE HE
DIDN'T SAY WHY, JUST HAVE THEM
COVER THEIR EYES.
AT 5, COVERING YOUR EYES AND
WALKING ISN'T SO EASY.
I HAD THEM LOOK TOWARDS THE WALL
AND WE WENT DOWN THE HALL AND
OUT OF THE BUILDING AND WE GOT
ON THE SIDEWALK AND I SAID, BOYS
AND GIRLS, REMEMBER THE
ADVENTURE WE HAD, WE ALL WALKED
TO THE FIREHOUSE, WE'RE GOING TO
DO THAT NOW AGAIN.
>> HOW ARE YOU HOLDING UP NOW?
YOU KNEW --
>> HOW AM I HOLDING UP NOW?
YOU KNEW A LOT OF THE KID KIDS.
>> I KNEW TEN OF THEM.
TEN OF THE KIDS WERE IN MY CLASS
LAST YEAR.
WHEN I HEARD THE NAMES, IT IS
TOUGH.
IT'S TOUGH.
I WAS WANTING TO ATTEND SOME OF
THE SERVICES.
I'M SURE SOME FAMILIES WANT
PRIVACY.
THERE IS A FEW CHILDREN WHO I'VE
HAD, NOT JUST THEM, I'VE HAD
THEIR SIBLINGS, AND IN ONE CASE
I'VE HAD ALL THREE.
SO THEIR FAMILIES WERE CLOSE.
AT SANDY HOOK SCHOOL, WE'RE A
TIGHT KNIT GROUP.
AND WE KNOW AND I LIVE IN THE
COMMUNITY ALSO.
>> YOU KNOW, SOMETHING ELSE
JANET VOLLMER POINTED OUT, THE
STUDENTS NEED TO COME BACK TO
SCHOOL, THEY NEED TO.
AT THIS POINT THEY ARE EXCUSED
UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE.
>>> 20 OF THE LIVES LOST HERE IN
THE CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTING,
THEY WERE CHILDREN.
JUST 6 OR 7-YEAR-OLDS.
AND DURING LAST NIGHT'S VIGIL AT
THE HIGH SCHOOL, PRESIDENT
OBAMA, HE READ EACH AND EVERY
ONE OF THEIR NAMES.
TAKE A LOOK.
>> LET THE LITTLE CHILDREN COME
TO ME, JESUS SAID.
AND DO NOT HINDER THEM.
FOR TO SUCH BELONGS THE KINGDOM
OF HEAVEN.
CHARLOTTE.
DANIEL.
OLIVIA.
JOSEPHINE.
ANA.
DYLAN.
MADELEINE.
CATHERINE.
CHASE.
JESSE.
JAMES.
GRACE.
EMILIE.
JACK.
NOAH.
CAROLINE.
JESSICA.
BENJAMIN.
AVIELLE.
ALLISON.
GOD HAS CALLED THEM ALL HOME.
FOR THOSE OF US WHO REMAIN, LET
US FIND THE STRENGTH TO CARRY ON
AND MAKE OUR COUNTRY WORTHY OF
THEIR MEMORY.
[ Male Announcer ] When Ziggy
the cat appeared at their door,
he opened up
Jake's very private world.
At first, Jake's family
thought they saved Ziggy,
but his connection with Jake
has been a lifesaver.
For a love this strong,
his family only feeds him Iams.
Compared to other
leading brands,
it has 50% more
animal protein...
...to help keep Ziggy's body
as strong as a love
that reaches further
than anyone's words.
Iams. Keep Love Strong.
>>> I'M BROOKE BALDWIN LIVE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE'LL HAVE MUCH MORE FROM HERE
IN JUST A MOMENT.
BUT FIRST, JOHN BERMAN IS IN NEW
YORK WITH SOME OF THE OTHER
STORIES OF THE DAY.
HEY, JOHN.
>> WE HAVE A BIG STORY COMING
OUT OF THE WHITE HOUSE RIGHT
NOW.
THE PRESIDENT MET AGAIN TODAY
WITH HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER
AFTER BOEHNER MADE TWO APPARENT
CONCESSIONS TOWARD AVERTING THE
SO-CALLED FISCAL CLIFF.
THE MEETING THIS TIME WAS ABOUT
45 MINUTES LONG.
OVER THE WEEKEND, THE SPEAKER
PROPOSED RAISING TAX RATES ON
THOSE MAKING OVER $1 MILLION A
YEAR.
CNN ALSO LEARNED THAT HE'S
PROPOSING A ONE-YEAR EXTENSION
OF THE GOVERNMENT'S BORROWING
LIMIT AND THAT COULD AVERT YET
ODD UGLY DEBT CEILING DEBATE.
A CONGRESSIONAL SOURCE TELLS US
IN EXCHANGE, SPEAKER BOEHNER IS
PUSHING FOR A TRILLION DOLLARS
IN SPENDING CUTS INCLUDING TO
MEDICARE, WHICH THE WHITE HOUSE
HAS OPPOSED.
AS FOR NOW, THE PRESIDENT IS
HOLDING FAST TO HIS DESIRE TO
RAISE TAX RATES ON INCOMES
BEGINNING AT $250,000.
>>> OVERSEAS, A VETERAN SYRIAN
STATESMAN RUMORED LAST SUMMER TO
HAVE DEFECTED, TODAY IS
PROPOSING A PEACEFUL END TO HIS
COUNTRY'S CIVIL WAR.
HE'S SAYING GOVERNMENT FORCES
CAN'T WIN AND NEITHER CAN THE
REBELS.
WE'LL HAVE THE STORY NOW FROM
LONDON.
HERE'S CNN'S NIC ROBERTSON.
>> THIS IS PRETTY STRONG STUFF
COMING FROM THE VICE PRESIDENT.
WE HAVEN'T HEARD THIS LANGUAGE
FROM ANYONE CLOSE TO THE SORT OF
INNER CIRCLE.
WHY SHOULD WE LISTEN TO FAROUK
AL SHARAA.
HE WAS THE FOREIGN MINISTER IN
THE COUNTRY.
SINCE THEN, THE VICE PRESIDENT.
HE'S BEEN UNDER HOUSE ARREST
SINCE THE SUMMER.
THERE HAVE BEEN REPORTS HE WAS
FLEEING THE COUNTRY.
THOSE PROVED NOT TO BE TRUE.
SO HE'S NOT SOMEBODY WHO IS
RIGHT AT THE RIGHT-HAND SIDE OF
BASHAR AL ASSAD RIGHT NOW.
BUT IT IS ABSOLUTELY UNUSUAL IN
THE CIRCUMSTANCES RIGHT NOW TO
HAVE SOMEBODY OF HIS STATURE
SAYING IT IS TIME FOR UNITY
GOVERNMENT.
HE GOES BEYOND THAT BY SAYING,
CRITICIZING BASHAR AL ASSAD
SAYING ASSAD ONLY WANTS TO HAVE
A POLITICAL SOLUTION AFTER A
MILITARY VICTORY.
AND HE SAYS THERE ARE PEOPLE IN
BASHAR AL ASSAD'S BAATH PARTY
THAT ACTUALLY SUPPORT A
POLITICAL SOLUTION NOW.
THAT PARTY LEADERS AROUND THE
COUNTRY, THE DEPARTMENTAL HEADS
AROUND THE COUNTRY, ONLY DO WHAT
BASHAR AL ASSAD SAYS.
HE BLAMES ASSAD FOR THAT.
HE SAID ASSAD LET THE ECONOMY OF
THE COUNTRY RUN DOWN.
THAT THAT'S THE REASON THAT
THESE PROTESTS BEGAN.
THAT BASHAR AL ASSAD IGNORED THE
PROTESTERS AND THAT'S WHY IT
TURNED TO VIOLENCE.
HE'S LAYING A LOT AT THE FEET OF
THE PRESIDENT HERE.
AND THIS DOES REALLY SEEM TO BE
THE FIRST TIME THAT WE'RE
GETTING INSIGHT FROM SOMEBODY
CLOSE TO THE INNER CIRCLE THAT
IS CALLING OUT AND SAYING IT IS
TIME FOR CHANGE.
HE SAYS THAT IF ASSAD DOESN'T
CHANGE, FIND SOME AGREEMENT WITH
THE OPPOSITION RIGHT NOW, IT
WILL BE TAKEN OUT OF HIS HANDS
AND INTO THE OPPOSITION WILL
HAVE THEIR WAY.
AND HE ALSO GOES ON TO CRITICIZE
THE REBELS AND SAYS ANYONE WHO
SITS DOWN AT THE TABLE NOW AND
EXPECTS TO GET EVERYTHING THAT
THEY WANT, THEN FORGET IT.
HE SAID THIS COUNTRY WILL
CONTINUE TO BE AT WAR.
THERE WILL BE FURTHER BLOODSHED
AND FURTHER SUFFERING.
SO HE'S PAINTING A VERY DARK
SCENARIO, BUT HE'S LAYING IT AT
THE FEET OF THE PRESIDENT SAYING
THAT BASHAR AL ASSAD MUST CHANGE
AND THE TIME TO DO THAT IS RIGHT
NOW, JOHN.
>> INTERESTING DEVELOPMENT.
A CRACK PERHAPS INSIDE THE
SYRIAN REGIME.
THANKS TO NIC ROBERTSON IN
LONDON.
NOW BACK TO NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
HEY, BROOKE.
>> JOHN BERMAN, THANKS SO MUCH.
>>> JUST INTO US, SENATOR DIANNE
FEINSTEIN TALKING TO CNN,
POIGNANT STATEMENT HERE, POINTED
ABOUT GUN CONTROL SPECIFICALLY
AS SHE'S TALKING THERE TO DANA
BASH.
SHE IS PUSHING FOR A BAN ON
ASSAULT WEAPONS.
WE WILL SHARE WITH YOU WHAT SHE
JUST REVEALED.
ALSO, DON LEMON, HE JOINS ME ON
HIS CONVERSATION WITH FRIENDS OF
THE GUNMAN'S MOTHER.
THAT'S NEXT.
It's hard to see opportunity
in today's challenging
environment.
Unless you have the right
perspective.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
has the vision
and experience to look beyond
the obvious.
We'll uncover opportunities,
find hidden risk,
and make success a reality.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
trying to find a better job can
Likbe frustrating.gs,
So at University of Phoenix
we're working with a growing
list of almost two thousand
corporate partners -
companies like Microsoft,
American Red Cross and Adobe -
to create options for you.
Not only that, we're using what
we learn from these partners
to shape our curriculum, so that
when you find the job you want
you'll be a perfect fit.
Let's get to work.
>>> THIS IS NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
AND THIS IS THE WEEK THE
FUNERALS BEGIN.
IN FACT, ONE IS BEGINNING JUST
ACROSS THE STREET.
THIS IS THE ONLY UNDERTAKER IN
THIS TOWN OF SOME 27,000 PEOPLE.
HE'S BEEN QUOTED AS SAYING THIS
IS A WEEK FROM HELL.
HE'S FACED WITH THE DAUNTING
TASK OF MASKING SOME OF THE
WOUNDS FROM FRIDAY'S SHOOTING.
AND WE'RE TOLD, THINK ABOUT
THESE TINY CASKETS, SOME WILL BE
OPEN, SOME WILL BE CLOSED.
WHAT IS HAPPENING ALL AROUND ME
IS THE FIREFIGHTERS HERE AT
SANDY HOOK FIRE AND RESCUE,
THEY'RE UNWRAPPING WREATHS FROM
ALL THE WAY ACROSS THE COUNTRY
IN PORTLAND, OREGON.
JUST TOLD ME THROUGH TEARS THERE
ARE 20.
20 FOR THE LITTLE LIVES LOST.
JUST DRIVING AROUND NEWTOWN, YOU
GET THE SENSE OF COMMUNITY AND
YOU SEE THESE MEMORIALS POPPING
UP, LIKE THIS ONE.
WE LOVE YOU, SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
HONK IF YOU LOVE US TOO.
SIGNS, GOD BLESS OUR TOWN, PRAY
FOR A TOWN.
WE NOTICED IN THE MIDDLE OF PART
OF TOWN A FLAG, THE BIG FLAG IS
NOW FLYING AT HALF-STAFF.
THIS IS THE FIREHOUSE HERE WHERE
A LOT OF THE FAMILIES HUDDLED
FRIDAY MORNING, LEARNING THE
FATES OF THEIR LITTLE SONS AND
DAUGHTERS.
WE CAN'T CROSS THE STREET.
YOU CAN SEE THE SIGN HERE, NO
MEDIA BEYOND THIS POINT.
WE CAN'T GET INSIDE THE
FIREHOUSE.
MANY OF THESE FIRST RESPONDERS
STILL VERY MUCH SO REELING OVER
WHAT THEY SAW, WHAT THEY
RESPONDED TO FRIDAY.
WANT TO READ YOU A QUOTE, FROM A
VOLUNTEER FIREFIGHTER, 39 YEARS
HERE, HE SAID I'VE SEEN SOME
HORRENDOUS THINGS IN 39 YEARS AS
A FIREFIGHTER.
THIS IS THE FIRST TIME I WENT
HOME AND CRIED.
I DID MANAGE TO TALK TO TWO
YOUNGER FIREFIGHTERS HERE AND
THEY TOLD ME REALLY THE
PRIORITY, BEYOND THE COMMUNITY,
THE GRIEF COUNSELORS, TO HELP
THEM COPE WITH WHAT THEY SAW.
SO THAT WAS JUST A LOOK AROUND
THE TOWN.
DON LEMON JOINS ME.
YOU'VE BEEN HERE FOR A COUPLE OF
DAYS.
I JUST CAN'T -- ALL THE ANGELS
IN PEOPLE'S FRONT YARDS AND THE
BALLOONS AND THE CHRISTMAS TREES
AND THE RIBBONS, IT IS
EVERYWHERE YOU TURN.
AND IN MEMORIAL OF THE LITTLE
LIVES LOST.
YOU WANT TO TALK MORE ABOUT THE
GUNMAN, ABOUT HIS MOTHER, WHAT
ARE YOU LEARNING?
>> WELL, NOT THAT, YOU KNOW,
EVERY TIME THERE IS SOMETHING
LIKE THIS, YOU WANT TO SHY AWAY
FROM MAKING THAT PERSON FAMOUS,
BUT THERE ARE SOME CLUES TO HIS
ACTIONS, POSSIBLY, AND TO FIND
OUT WHY --
>> WHY.
>> WHY, WHICH IS WHAT EVERYONE
IS ASKING.
YOU HAVE TO GO TO THE PEOPLE WHO
KNEW HIM.
HIS MOTHER'S FRIENDS, I TALKED
TO THEM ABOUT THE MOTHER,
BECAUSE THEY WANT TO TALK ABOUT
HER, I ASKED THEM ABOUT HIM.
WHAT WAS HE LIKE?
WERE THERE ANY WARNING SIGNS?
LISTEN.
YOU KNEW ADAM?
>> YEAH.
>> WHAT ABOUT HIM?
>> HE DID HAVE ASPERGER'S
SYNDROME.
HE, LIKE MANY KIDS THAT HAVE
THAT, HE WAS VERY WITHDRAWN,
EMOTIONALLY.
BUT HE HAD -- HE WAS AN ORGANIC
VEGAN AND NOBODY SEEMS TO KNOW
THAT.
AND HE TOOK THAT STANCE BECAUSE
OF MORAL STANCE ABOUT ANIMALS
PROVIDING HIS FOOD.
HE DIDN'T WANT TO REQUIRE THEM
TO MAKE THAT SACRIFICE.
HE BELIEVED THAT NOTHING SHOULD
HAVE TO DIE SO HE COULD LIVE.
SO IT MAKES THE ENORMITY OF THIS
TRAGEDY EVEN MORE BIZARRE,
BECAUSE HE WAS NOT VIOLENT.
HE DIDN'T HAVE A PROBLEM WITH
ANYBODY.
HE WAS VERY RECLUSIVE.
HE WAS VERY PRIVATE IN TERMS OF
HOW HE VIEWED HIMSELF AND HE WAS
ALWAYS TRYING TO BE VERY
INCONSPICUOUS, EVEN IN PUBLIC.
HE DIDN'T WANT TO MAKE THEM --
HIMSELF THE CENTER OF ATTENTION.
HE NEVER WAS -- ALWAYS A VERY
QUIET KID.
>> HE WASN'T A BAD KID.
>> NO.
NOT AT ALL.
>> HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN THIS?
>> I DON'T.
I THINK WE'RE ALL -- WE'RE ALL
DOWN HERE LOOKING FOR ANSWERS.
>> SO HE'S QUIET, HE'S A LONE
E
ER, RECLUSIVE.
THOSE ARE THE SIGNS OF --
THEY'RE NOT MUTUALLY EXCLUSIVE,
BUT THOSE ARE THE SIGNS THAT
PSYCHOLOGISTS AND THAT PROFILERS
WILL TELL YOU THAT MIGHT LEAD
PEOPLE TO -- SO THEY -- THERE
WERE SOME WARNING SIGNS THERE,
BUT DIDN'T THINK THERE WERE ANY
WARNING SIGNS THERE.
ALSO, THEY SAID, THEY DON'T
BELIEVE HE HAD ANY CONNECTION TO
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
BUT HE DID GO TO SANDY HOOK HIGH
SCHOOL.
SO, BUT NO CONNECTION, THEY
BELIEVE TO THE --
>> TALKING TO AN EXPERT A MOMENT
AGO AND HIS POINT WAS THAT IF
YOU GET TO A POINT, YOU DO NOT
DISTINGUISH CHILDREN VERSUS
ADULTS, PERHAPS, IN THIS CASE.
NO ONE WILL FULLY UNDERSTAND
WHY.
I WANT TO TALK ABOUT THIS NEW
POLL.
TAKE A LOOK AT THE NUMBERS HERE,
A NEW POLL, TAKEN AFTER FRIDAY'S
SHOOTINGS AND YOU LOOK AT THE
NUMBER HERE IN A MOMENT.
44% OF AMERICANES SAY THEY
STRONGLY SUPPORT STRICTER GUN
CONTROL LAWS.
THAT IS UP JUST A LITTLE BIT
FROM 39% BACK IN AUGUST.
THAT WAS AFTER THE AURORA
THEATER SHOOTINGS IN COLORADO.
THE ABC "WASHINGTON POST" SURVEY
SHOWS 32% OPPOSE STRICTER GUN
CONTROL LAWS, THAT'S DOWN FROM
37% IN AUGUST.
THE PUSH FOR NEW GUN CONTROL
LAWS ALREADY IN THE WORKS.
DIANNE FEINSTEIN PLANS TO
REINTRODUCE HER ASSAULT BAN --
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN LEGISLATION.
WE TALKED SO MUCH ABOUT THAT.
ALSO NEW JERSEY SENATOR FRANK
LAUTENBERG PLANS A BILL THAT
WOULD BAN THE SALE OF HIGH
CAPACITY MAGAZINES.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> WHY DO YOU THINK THIS MOMENT
MAY BE DIFFERENT?
>> BECAUSE I THINK IT IS A
LOGICAL CONTINUUM.
IF THERE SHOULD BE A SAFE PLACE
IN AMERICA, IT IS AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
AND HERE IN THIS ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, LOOK WHAT HAPPENED.
6-YEAR-OLDS WITH 3 TO 11 BULLETS
FROM THIS BUSHMASTER IN THEIR
BODY, 20 OF THEM.
IS THIS AMERICA?
I DON'T THINK SO.
AND I THINK THESE INCIDENTS ARE
GOING TO CONTINUE UNTIL WE DO
SOMETHING TO CHANGE THE SUPPLY
MODE OF THESE WEAPONS OUT IN OUR
SOCIETY.
>> IT IS A GRUESOME IMAGE TO
THINK ABOUT.
BUT HOW SHE SAID, THIS IS
AMERICA.
I DON'T THINK SO.
HERE YOU HAVE THE PRESIDENT HERE
IN TOWN, JUST LAST NIGHT,
SPEAKING AT THE HIGH SCHOOL,
AND, YOU KNOW, IF YOU LISTEN TO
HIM, HE DIDN'T GO INTO
SPECIFICS, BUT HE CERTAINLY SAID
THAT GUN VIOLENCE, KILLING
AMERICA'S YOUTH MUST SOP.
.
>> WE CAN'T TOLERATE THIS
ANYMORE.
THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
AND TO END THEM WE MUST CHANGE.
>> SO SUPPORTERS OF GUN RIGHTS,
THEY SEEM TO BE SAYING, YOU
KNOW, YES, WE NEED MORE GUNS,
BUT I DON'T KNOW HOW THAT
MOMENTUM IS REALLY SHIFTING.
>> HERE'S THE THING.
CAN WE GO BACK TO WHAT DIANNE
FEINSTEIN --
>> HOW ABOUT WHAT SHE SAID.
>> HERE'S THE THING.
>> YEAH.
>> IF YOU ASK -- LISTEN, WE'RE
COMING OFF OF 20 KIDS BEING
SHOT.
THESE ARE 6 AND 7-YEAR-OLDS.
THESE ARE KIDS WHO, AS I'VE BEEN
SAYING, GOING TO BOLT DOWN THE
STAIRS IN A FEW DAYS TO SEE WHAT
SANTA BROUGHT THEM.
THINK ABOUT THAT.
>> RIGHT.
>> DOES YOUR RIGHT -- DO YOU
BELIEVE YOUR RIGHT TO OWN A GUN
OR AN ASSAULT WEAPON, WE'RE NOT
TALKING ABOUT TAKING AWAY
PEOPLE'S GUNS, AN ASSAULT WEAPON
OR AUTOMATIC RIVFLE, DOES THAT
TRUMP MY RIGHT TO BE IN A MOVIE
THEATER AND FEEL SAFE, A 6 AND
7-YEAR-OLD TO SIT IN A CLASSROOM
AND FEEL SAFE?
I DON'T THINK SO.
SO THAT'S THE CONVERSATION WE
NEED TO HAVE.
AND WHEN SOMEONE SAYS, OH, WELL,
PEOPLE WHO SAY WE NEED TO LOOK
AT THE GUN LAWS ARE TRYING TO
TAKE AWAY THE SECOND AMENDMENT
RIGHT, NOT AT ALL.
BUT IN THE WAKE OF CHILDREN
BEING SLAUGHTERED IN AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, IF WE'RE NOT
GOING TO TALK ABOUT IT NOW, WHEN
THE HECK ARE WE GOING TO TALK
ABOUT IT?
IT IS DISRESPECTFUL NOT TO DO IT
AT THIS POINT.
I THINK IT WOULD BE
DISRESPECTFUL NOT ONLY --
>> SOME PEOPLE ARE FRUSTRATED
WE'RE HAVING THIS CONVERSATION
AT ALL AND TRYING TO POLITICIZE
IT OR MEMBERS OF CONGRESS ARE
TRYING TO POLITICIZE IT.
BUT I AGREE.
>> WE'RE VERY GOOD AT LIGHTING
CANDLES, AND SAYING ALL THE
RIGHT THINGS, AND THEN WE'RE ON
TO THE NEXT TRAGEDY.
IT WILL BE ANOTHER SHOOTING, A
HURRICANE, A TWISTER.
>> I DON'T WANT TO COVER ANOTHER
ONE OF THESE.
>> THANK YOU.
>> I DON'T WANT TO COVER ANOTHER
ONE OF THESE.
DON, THANK YOU.
>>> COMING UP, DAN MALLOY SET TO
GIVE A NEWS CONFERENCE ANY
MOMENT NOW FROM HARTFORD,
CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE WATCHING THAT.
WE'LL BRING IT TO YOU LIVE.
HAVE A GOOD NIGHT.
HERE YOU GO. YOU, TOO.
I'M GOING TO DREAM
ABOUT THAT STEAK.
ABOUT THAT TIRAMISU.
WHAT A NIGHT, HUH?
BUT, UM, CAN THE TEST DRIVE
BE OVER NOW?
HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A PASSAT.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN, $0 DUE AT SIGNING,
$0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
>>> FROM NEW YORK, I'M ALI
VELSHI.
THIS IS YOUR MONEY.
HOW BIG SHOULD GOVERNMENT BE AND
WHAT ARE YOU WAILING TO PAY FOR
IT?
THERE ARE 15 DAYS LEFT TO AVERT
THE FISCAL CLIFF AND REPUBLICANS
ARE FINALLY OFFERING TO INCREASE
TAX RATES ON THE WEALTHY.
SPEAKER BOEHNER PROPOSED AN
INCREASE ON FAMILIES MAKING A
MILLION BUCKS OR MORE.
THE WHITE HOUSE SAYS IT IS NOT
ENOUGH.
BUT IT IS A STEP IN THE RIGHT
DIRECTION.
BOEHNER WAS BACK AT THE WHITE
HOUSE TODAY TO TALK ABOUT IT
SOME MORE.
REPUBLICANS MAY BE BENDING
SLIGHTLY BUT GENERALLY OPPOSE
MORE REVENUE BECAUSE THEY FEEL
GOVERNMENT ALREADY SPENDS TOO
MUCH.
SO THE QUESTION IS NOT REALLY
ABOUT WHETHER MILLIONAIRES OR
THOSE MAKING MORE THAN $250,000
A YEAR WILL PAY HIGHER RATES,
THE REAL CONVERSATION BOILS DOWN
TO THE ROLE OF GOVERNMENT.
FAREED ZAKARIA WERE DISCUSSING
MY CONTENTION WE SHOULD BE LESS
CONCERNED WITH ACTUAL RATES AND
BE HAVING MORE OF A DISCUSSION
ABOUT THE VALUE THAT AMERICANS
GET FOR THEIR TAX DOLLARS.
>> HERE'S THE PROBLEM WITH THAT.
AMERICANS LIKE GOVERNMENT.
SO WHAT WE HAVE FOR THE LAST 30
YEARS, DON, IS SAY WE'RE GOING
TO HAVE LOW TAXES, BUT WE STILL
WANT LOTS OF GOVERNMENT.
WE MADE UP THAT DIFFERENCE BY
BORROWING.
>> SPEAKING OF VALUE FOR YOUR
TAXES, LOOK AT THIS LIST OF
COUNTRIES RATED ON A 1 TO 10
LIFE SATISFACTION SCALE.
DENMARK TOPS THE LIST.
CANADA AT 9.
U.S. AT 8.
FRANCE AT 7 AND JAPAN A MEASLY
4.
LOOK AT THE TOP TAX RATES IN
THESE COUNTRIES.
AMERICANS PAY 41.7% WHEN YOU
FACTOR IN FEDERAL, STATE AND
LOCAL TAXES.
DANS ARE HAPPY BUT PAY MORE,
48%.
WHY?
IN PART BECAUSE THEIR TAXES GET
THEM FREE HEALTH CARE AND POST
SECONDARY EDUCATION.
SO, PERHAPS A MORE CONSTRUCTIVE
CONVERSATION SHOULD CENTER ON
HOW MUCH WE EXPECT TO BENEFIT
FROM GOVERNMENT SERVICES, AND
HOW MUCH WE'RE WILLING TO PAY
FOR THOSE SERVICES.
NOW, THE NEGOTIATION BETWEEN
SPEAKER BOEHNER AND PRESIDENT
OBAMA HAVE GIVEN US A NEW TERM
OVER WHICH TO OBSESS, CHAIN CPI.
IT WOULD CHANGE THE WAY THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT CALCULATES
INFLATION AND THOSE BENEFITS
THAT ARE TIED TO IT.
NORMALLY EVERY YEAR BOTH WAGES
AND PRICES GO UP.
THE CONSUMER PRICE INDEX OR CPI
MEASURES HOW MUCH PRICES GO UP
BY TRACKING A BASKET OF GOODS
THAT AMERICANS TYPICALLY BUY.
THIS IS USED TO CALCULATE COST
OF LIVING ADJUSTMENTS ON SOCIAL
SECURITY.
CHECKS PAY A LITTLE MORE EACH
YEAR AS PRICES FOR WHAT WE NEED
GO UP.
ONE POTENTIAL FLAW IN THE SYSTEM
IS THAT CPI ASSUMES PEOPLE DON'T
CHANGE THE THINGS IN THE BASKET.
IF YOU'RE EATING MORE CHICKEN
BECAUSE THE PRICE OF BEEF HAS
SHOT UP, CPI DOESN'T ACCOUNT FOR
THAT.
CHAIN CPI CREATES A CHAINED
BASKETS OF GOODS TO MEASURE
INFLATION MORE ACCURATELY.
IT IS MEASURING HOW PEOPLE
ACTUALLY REACT TO PRICE CHANGES,
NOT SIMPLY THE FACT THAT PRICES
HAVE CHANGED.
CHAIN CPI WOULD ACCOUNT FOR THE
FACT YOU ARE BUYING MORE
CHICKEN, WHEN BEEF BECOMES TOO
EXPENSIVE.
NOW THAT COULD RESULT IN A
SLOWER RATE OF INFLATION OVER
TIME, SAVING THE GOVERNMENT
MONEY ON THOSE COST OF LIVING
ADJUSTMENTS.
AND ON RAISING TAX BRACKETS ON
WHAT PEOPLE EARN.
SO WHY IS CHAIN CPI SUDDENLY SO
VITAL TO THE FISCAL CLIFF
NEGOTIATION?
WELL, IT ISN'T A SPENDING CUT,
OR A TAX HIKE.
BUT IT WILL EFFECTIVELY CUT
SPENDING AND RAISE TAXES ON
SOME, SAVING THE GOVERNMENT AN
ESTIMATED $300 BILLION OVER THE
NEXT DECADE.
FROM NEW YORK, I'M ALI VELSHI.
TALK TO YOU SAME TIME TOMORROW.
.
OMNIPOTENT OF OPPORTUNITY.
YOU KNOW HOW TO MIX BUSINESS...
WITH BUSINESS.
AND YOU...RENT FROM NATIONAL.
BECAUSE ONLY NATIONAL LETS YOU
CHOOSE ANY CAR IN THE AISLE.
AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE A FULL-SIZE
OR ABOVE.
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
I COULD GET USED TO THIS.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, YOU COULD BUSINESS PRO.
YES, YOU COULD.
GO NATIONAL. GO LIKE A PRO.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OUR TENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
♪
BECOMING
PART OF THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
TREES WILL TALK TO NETWORKS
WILL TALK TO SCIENTISTS
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE.
CARS WILL TALK TO ROAD SENSORS
WILL TALK TO STOPLIGHTS
ABOUT TRAFFIC EFFICIENCY.
THE AMBULANCE WILL TALK
TO PATIENT RECORDS
WILL TALK TO DOCTORS
ABOUT SAVING LIVES.
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
THE NEXT BIG THING?
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
♪
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
♪
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
♪ HARK HOW THE BELLS,
SWEET SILVER BELLS ♪
♪ ALL SEEM TO SAY
THROW CARE AWAY ♪
♪ FROM EVERYWHERE,
FILLING THE AIR ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
CHEX PARTY MIX.
EASY 15-MINUTE
HOMEMADE RECIPES
YOU JUST POP IN A MICROWAVE.
LIKE CARAMEL CHOCOLATE
DRIZZLES.
HAPPIER HOLIDAYS.
CHEX PARTY MIX.
>>> BACK HERE LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WHERE PEOPLE DAYS
AFTER THE SHOOTING ON FRIDAY ARE
JUST BEGINNING TO WRAP THEIR
HEADS AROUND THIS GRIEF.
WE ARE NOW ABOUT TO HEAR FROM,
IN FACT, HERE HE IS, THE
GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT HERE,
DAN MALLOY, SPEAKING AT THE
STATE CAPITAL.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> -- I WOULD ASK IF THEY ARE
QUESTIONS DIRECTLY AND
SPECIFICALLY RELATED TO THE
INVESTIGATION OF THE INCIDENT
THAT YOU REFER THOSE QUESTIONS
TO LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE, WHO,
BY THE WAY, I THINK IS DOING AN
OUTSTANDING JOB, IN KEEPING YOU
ALL APPRAISED OF THE
CIRCUMSTANCES THAT TOOK PLACE AT
THE SCHOOL.
THE LIEUTENANT GOVERNOR AND I
EACH ATTENDED A FUNERAL SERVICE
TODAY.
I ATTENDED NOAH'S FUNERAL IN
FAIRFIELD AND THE LIEUTENANT
GOVERNOR ATTENDED JACK'S FUNERAL
IN NEWTOWN.
THERE REALLY ARE NO WORDS TO
DESCRIBE WHAT IT IS LIKE TO SEE
THESE PARENTS AS I DID ON
FRIDAY, LAST NIGHT, GOING FROM
ROOM TO ROOM, AND THEN AGAIN
WITH RESPECT TO NOAH'S PARENTS
TODAY.
IT IS TOUGH TO SEE RELATIVES AND
FRIENDS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN, WHO DIED, AND AS WELL
AS TO SEE SOME OF THE TEACHERS
WHO HAVE BEEN SO ADVERSELY
IMPACTED.
THE REALITY WITH RESPECT TO THE
RELATIVES AS YOU TRY TO FEEL
THEIR PAIN, BUT YOU CAN'T, YOU
TRY TO FIND SOME WORDS THAT YOU
HOPE WILL BE ADEQUATE, KNOWING
THAT THEY'LL BE INADEQUATE AND
YOU SEE LITTLE COFFINS AND YOUR
HEART HAS TO ACHE.
SO YOU TELL THEM, YOU GRIEVE FOR
THEIR LOSS, YOU GIVE THEM A HUG
AND YOU TELL THEM THAT THEIR
COMMUNITY, THEIR STATE, AND
THEIR NATION, DARE I SAY THE
WHOLE WORLD, STANDS WITH THEM
AND YOU HOPE THAT THAT MAKES
SOME DIFFERENCE.
PAST FEW DAYS HAVE OBVIOUSLY
BEEN VERY DIFFICULT ONES FOR
ANYONE LIVING IN THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT OR AWARE OF THESE
PARTICULARLY HEINOUS
CIRCUMSTANCES.
AS I SAID IN MY TELEVISED
REMARKS ON SATURDAY NIGHT, YOU
SEE THESE TRAGEDIES PLAY OUT IN
OTHER PLACES, AND YOU HOPE AND
YOU EXPECT THAT IT WILL NEVER
HAPPEN IN YOUR HOME, BUT CLEARLY
IT DID IN CONNECTICUT.
I WILL REPEAT SOMETHING I SAID
ON FRIDAY AND SATURDAY.
THE FAMILIES OF THOSE VICTIMS,
THEIR FAMILIES, THEIR RELATIVES,
THE BRAVE TEACHERS AND
ADMINISTRATORS AT THE SCHOOL WHO
SURVIVED AND THE CHILDREN WHO
SURVIVED, TO ALL OF THEM, LET
US -- LET ME SAY ON BEHALF OF
THE STATE OF CONNECTICUT WE
STAND READY TO ASSIST YOU IN ANY
WAY POSSIBLE, IN ANY WAY NEEDED
TO HELP YOU HEAL.
SO MANY RESOURCES ALREADY
BEING -- SO MANY RESOURCES ARE
ALREADY BEING BROUGHT TO BEAR,
BUT WE WILL BRING MORE, WHATEVER
IS NECESSARY, AND DO WHATEVER
HAS TO BE DONE TO HELP OUR STATE
AND THE COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN AND
SPECIFIC NEIGHBORHOOD OF SANDY
HOOK HEAL.
TO THAT END, AND THIS IS FOR ALL
OF OUR CITIZENS, NOT JUST ON A
GEOGRAPHIC BASIS, ANYONE WHO IS
HURTING IN THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT, CALL 211, IT IS A
CRISIS LINE, IT IS AVAILABLE ON
A STATE WIDE BASIS, IT IS
AVAILABLE 24 HOURS A DAY TO
CONNECT FAMILIES WITH RESOURCES
THAT THEY NEED TO GET THROUGH
THESE CIRCUMSTANCES.
AND IT IS STAFFED BY PEOPLE WHO
IT IS STAFFED BY PEOPLE WHO ARE
TRAINED SPECIALISTS IN HANDLING
THESE SITUATIONS.
WE'VE USED THE UNITED WAY AND
211 TO HELP COORDINATE THE MANY
OFFERS OF SERVICES THAT ARE
POURING IN TO OUR STATE.
AND WE WILL USE MANY OF THOSE
RESOURCES I'M SURE.
I WANT TO AGAIN THANK THE
PRESIDENT FOR HAVING COME TO THE
STATE AND HAVING PLEDGED TO
PROVIDE ON BEHALF OF THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT THE PRESENCE THAT WE
NEEDED IN NEWTOWN AND ANY
ADDITIONAL SERVICES.
I ALSO WANT TO COMMENT THAT HE
WAS ELOQUENT, HE WAS MOVING, HE
WAS HEALING AND HE WAS POWERFUL.
I THINK I CAN SPEAK ON BEHALF OF
EVERYONE WHEN I SAY WE'RE
GRATEFUL FOR HIS LEADERSHIP AND
OBVIOUS THAT HE IS CONCERNED
ABOUT OUR STATE AND OUR PEOPLE
AND I'M MOST APPRECIATIVE OF
THAT.
I WANT TO THANK THE FIRST
RESPONDERS.
IT'S PRETTY CLEAR NOW THAT THEIR
VERY QUICK RESPONSE SAVED LIVES.
WE ARE GRATEFUL TO THEM.
THEY PUT THEIR LIVES ON THE LINE
EVERY SINGLE DAY.
THEN THERE ARE DAYS LIKE FRIDAY
WHEN THEY PUT THEIR LIVES ON THE
LINE AND THEY ACTUALLY SAVE
LIVES AS THEY CLEARLY DID ON
FRIDAY.
AS A RESULT, CHILDREN WENT HOME
AND CONTINUED THEIR PREPARATIONS
TO CELEBRATE CHRISTMAS OR
HANUKKAH.
I WOULD LIKE TO THANK THE ADULTS
IN THE SCHOOL, THE TEACHERS, THE
ADMINISTRATORS, ALL OF THE
ADULTS.
THOSE WHO DIED TRYING TO SAVE
THEIR STUDENTS ARE HEROES.
THEY GAVE THEIR LIVES SO OTHERS
COULD LIVE.
AND THERE ARE THOSE TEACHERS WHO
SAVED MANY LIVES, THEY ARE HERO
ALSO.
THERE ARE A LOT OF HEROES IN
CONNECTICUT TODAY AND I'M
GRATEFUL TO ALL OF THEM.
I SAID IN MY REMARKS SATURDAY
NIGHT THAT I THOUGHT THERE WOULD
BE A TIME FOR PUBLIC DISCUSSION
AND THAT DISCUSSION WOULD
INEVITABLY OCCUR.
AS IT DOES EVERY TIME WHEN A
TRAGEDY LIKE THIS TAKES PLACE.
AND I THINK SOME PEOPLE
INTERPRETED THAT TO MEAN THAT I
THOUGHT IT WAS INAPPROPRIATE FOR
THOSE DISCUSSIONS TO TAKE PLACE.
I DO NOT THINK IT'S
INAPPROPRIATE FOR THEM TO TAKE
PLACE.
IN FACT, IT'S QUITE APPROPRIATE.
THE POINT I WAS MAKING WAS THAT
NO MORE THAN 36 HOURS AFTER THE
EVENT, MY JOB, MY PERSONAL JOB
AS GOVERNOR AT THAT MOMENT, WAS
TO SPEAK TO THE PEOPLE OF
CONNECTICUT ABOUT THE FEARS
THEY'RE FEELING, THE DAMAGE
THAT'S BEEN DONE, AND MY JOB WAS
TO HELP AND CONTINUE TO HELP
NEWTOWN AND THE ENTIRE STATE TO
RECOVER.
BUT WE KNOW IN OUR STATE WE HAVE
SOME OF THE TOUGHEST LAWS IN THE
NATION.
I'M GOING TO ASK A FEW
QUESTIONS.
IS THERE A LAW, A POLICY, WE
COULD HAVE HAD ON THE BOOKS THAT
MIGHT HAVE PREVENTED THIS
STRATEGY?
IT TURNS OUT QUITE CLEARLY THE
ANSWER IS YES, I BELIEVE IT IS
YES, AND WE SHOULD PURSUE THAT
STRATEGY.
ARE WE DOING ENOUGH TO REACH OUT
TO KIDS AND FAMILIES WHO ARE
OBVIOUSLY IN TROUBLE?
MY SENSE IS WE ARE NOT AND WE
NEED TO LOOK AT THAT WITHIN OUR
OWN STATE AND WITHIN OUR OWN
NATION.
FINALLY, DO I THINK WASHINGTON,
D.C. NEEDS TO GET ITS ACT
TOGETHER AND ENACT STRICTER GUN
CONTROL LAWS AT THE FEDERAL
LEVEL?
YOU BET I DO.
I'M CONFIDENT, ESPECIALLY AFTER
HEARING THE PRESIDENT AND HIS
ADDRESS TODAY THAT PERHAPS --
AND THE COMMENTS OF OUR OWN
DELEGATE ORGANIZATION THAT
PERHAPS THE DEBATE WILL BE
RENEWED IN WASHINGTON AND LEAD
TO A DIFFERENT RESULT, ONE OTHER
THAN THE RESULT THAT ALLOWED THE
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN TO HAVE
EXPIRED.
THE DEBATE IS ALREADY PLAYING
OUT ON THE NATIONAL LEVEL.
IF CONNECTICUT OR I CAN BE A
VOICE ON THAT LEVEL, WE ARE
PREPARED TO ENTER THAT STATE
RIGHT NOW.
OUR FOCUS NOW IS TO HELP GET
THROUGH THIS TERRIBLE TIME.
FIRST, OFFERS OF FINANCIAL
ASSISTANCE, GENEROUS OFFER, ARE
POURING IN.
I'VE ASKED MY STAFF TO HANDLE
ALL OF THIS IN AN ORGANIZED
FASHION.
I EXPECT TO HAVE SOMETHING
FURTHER TO ANNOUNCE ABOUT THIS
IN THE NEXT DAY OR TWO.
I KNOW THAT THE COMMUNITY OF NEW
TOWN IS WORKING WITH UNITED WAY
ON THIS VERY SUBJECT AS WELL AND
HAS SET UP A FUND THERE.
SECOND, I'VE SIGNED AN EXECUTIVE
ORDER THAT WILL PERMIT MONROE
AND NEWTOWN TO ENTER INTO AN
AGREEMENT CONCERNI INING THE US
A MONROE EXTRA SCHOOL THEY HAVE,
SURPLUS SCHOOL, THAT WILL ALLOW
THAT SCHOOL TO BE USED
IMMEDIATELY AND SUSPENDS SOME OF
THE PUBLIC NOTICE ASPECTS OF
ENTERING INTO THAT AGREEMENT.
OBVIOUSLY, THIS IS AN EMERGENCY.
I WAS PREPARED TO DECLARE A
SEPARATE EMERGENCY, BUT THE
REALITY IS, WE'RE STILL UNDER
HURRICANE SANDY EMERGENCY SO I
USED THAT AS THE BASIS TO
EXECUTE THAT EXECUTIVE ORDER.
THIRD, I'M ASKING FRIDAY,
DECEMBER 21st, AT 9:30 A.M.,
EXACTLY ONE WEEK AFTER THE
HORROR BEGAN TO UNFOLD IN
NEWTOWN, THAT THE ENTIRE STATE
OBSERVE A MOMENT OF SILENCE.
I'D LIKE TO ASK HOUSES OF
WORSHIP WITH THE ABILITY TO PLAY
BELLS TO DO SO.
26 BELLS FOR THE BEAUTIFUL
CHILDREN AND 6 WONDERFUL ADULTS
WHO WERE KILLED AT THE SCHOOL ON
THAT DAY.
I'LL BE SENDING A LETTER OF
NOTIFICATION TO ALL OF THE OTHER
GOVERNORS THROUGH THE NGA TO ASK
THEM TO ASK THEIR CITIZENS TO
OBSERVE THAT OCCASION AS WELL.
NOW I'M HAPPY TO TAKE YOUR
QUESTIONS.
>> GOVERNOR, WHILE THE FEDERAL
ASSAULT BAN HAS EXPIRED, THE
STATE BAN HERE IN CONNECTICUT
REMAINS IN EFFECT.
HAS BEEN SINCE 1993.
SEEMS UNCLEAR WHETHER OR NOT
THIS WEAPON THAT WAS SEIZED AT
THIS INCIDENT WAS COVERED BY IT
OR NOT.
WE ALSO HAVE A UNIQUE LAW ON THE
BOOKS THAT WAS ENACTED A COUPLE
OF YEARS AFTER THE LOTTERY
SHOOTINGS, WHICH ALLOWS YOU TO
REPORT SOMEONE WHO YOU THINK IS
DANGEROUS AND HAS WEAPONS IN THE
HOUSE.
I THINK IT'S CALLED THE WEAPONS
SEIZURE LAW.
SOME PEOPLE CALL IT "REPORT YOUR
NEIGHBOR" LAW, YOU KNOW THE ONE
I'M TALKING ABOUT.
THOSE ARE TWO OF THE TOUGHEST
LAWS ON THE BOOKS IN THE
COUNTRY, YET NEITHER ONE OF THEM
HELPED HERE.
A MAN SHOT HIS WAY INTO THE
SCHOOL.
IS THERE REALLY ANYTHING ELSE
THAT COULD BE DONE --
>> SURE --
>> -- TO STOP THING LIKE --
>> NUMBER ONE, WE DO USE THE
LATTER OF THE TWO STATUTES
YOU'VE REFERRED TO.
I THINK WE'VE REMOVED THOUSANDS
OF GUNS USING THAT STATUTE.
SECONDLY WITH RESPECT TO THE
EXPIRING -- WHAT WAS OTHERWISE
THE BRADY BILL OR THE ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN, UNDER THAT
LEGISLATION, CLIPS WERE LIMITED
TO TEN.
WE KNOW THAT IN THIS CASE CLIPS
WERE USED WITH 30 CARTRIDGES AND
MULTIPLES WERE USED.
THAT ONE DIFFERENCE COULD VERY
WELL HAVE BEEN SIGNIFICANT, AND
I SUSPECT IT WOULD HAVE BEEN.
YOU KNOW, THESE GUNS AREN'T USED
TO HUNT DEER, AND, YOU KNOW, I'M
A BIG BELIEVER IN HUNTING
RIGHTS, BIG BELIEVER IN
SUPPORTING THE SECOND AMENDMENT.
BUT THERE IS A REALITY THAT THIS
STUFF HAS GONE TOO FAR, AND IS
TOO EASY TO OWN, AND THEN
YOUR -- THE WHOLE POINT OF YOUR
QUESTION IS THAT CONNECTICUT HAS
THESE LAWS.
IN THE ABSENCE OF A FEDERAL
FRAMEWORK IN WHICH WE LIMIT
REALLY THE EXPLOSIVE NATURE OF
THE WEAPONS AND AMMUNITION
THAT'S USED, NO STATE WOULD EVER
BE SAFE BASED ON SIMPLY ITS OWN
LAWS.
THAT'S WHY THE BRADY BILL, THE
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN WAS SO
IMPORTANT.
POLITICS PLAYED A ROLE INTO
ALLOWING THAT TO EXPIRE.
POLITIC SHOGS PLAY A ROLE IN
HAVING IT BE REINSTITUTED.
WE CAN'T BUILD A BUILDING ANY
FASTER THAN THEY CAN BUILD A
BUILDING.
YOU KNOW, THAT'S A LOCAL ISSUE
TO BE DISCUSSED AND WE'LL
RT