>>> A SMALL STEP BACK TO NORMAL
TODAY IN THIS CONNECTICUT TOWN
THAT IS SCARRED FOREVER.
MOST NEWTOWN STUDENTS WENT BACK
TO SCHOOL FOR THE FIRST TIME
SINCE THE MASSACRE WITH POLICE
STANDING GUARD.
TWO MORE YOUNG VICTIMS ARE
BURIED, AND THE MAN INVOLVED IN
THE INVESTIGATION TELLS ME ABOUT
THE HORRORS HE SAW INSIDE THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> THE CRIME SCENE ITSELF IS
SOMETHING THAT HAS MADE A MARK
IN ALL OF OUR MINDS.
THE TASK OF THAT RESPONSIBILITY
WITH THE CRIME SCENE IS
SOMETHING THAT WE WILL NEVER BE
ABLE TO ERASE.
>> THERE WILL NEVER BE A GOOD
ENOUGH EXPLANATION WHY 20
ELEMENTARY STUDENTS WERE GUNNED
DOWN BUT WE ALL NEED ANSWERS.
I'M WOLF BLITZER REPORTING FROM
NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT.
STATE POLICE IS WORKING AROUND
THE CLOCK.
THEIR INVESTIGATION OF THE
SCHOOL MASSACRE IS VERY
METHODICAL AND VERY, VERY
PAINFUL.
JOINING US NOW, LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE.
HE'S BECOME THE FACE, THE
SPOKESMAN OF THIS INVESTIGATION.
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE.
LIEUTENANT VANCE, WE'RE HERE IN
YOUR OFFICE IN MIDDLETOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
I KNOW IT MUST BE HARD ON THE
JOURNALISTS SO IT MUST BE SO
MUCH MORE HARD ON THE MEN AND
WOMEN THAT WORK AT THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE.
WHAT HAS IT BEEN LIKE?
>> IT'S BEEN A HORRIBLE, TRAGIC
SCENE.
THE INITIAL RESPONSE WAS JUST
HORRIFIC.
THE MEN AND WOMAN THAT RISKED
THEIR LIVES GOING IN THERE
TRYING TO STOP THE AGGRESSION,
TRYING TO STOP THE SHOOTING AND
CARNAGE AND RESCUE AS MANY
PEOPLE AS THEY COULD TRULY PUT
THEIR LIVES ON THE LINE BUT EVEN
MORE SO, THE FACULTY, THE STAFF,
THE TEACHERS THAT TRIED AND DID
PROTECT MANY OF THOSE CHILDREN.
THERE'S GOOD AND BAD BUT OUR
HEARTS ARE JUST SIMPLY BROKEN
JUST DUE TO THE FACT THAT 26
PEOPLE DIED IN THAT BUILDING.
>> HOW ARE THE MEN AND WOMEN OF
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE,
THE FIRST RESPONDERS, HOW ARE
THEY DOING?
>> THEY ARE WORKING THROUGH
THIS.
WE PROVIDE COUNSELING AND
EMPLOYEE ASSISTANCE TO THEM.
THEY ARE HUMAN BEINGS ALSO BUT
WE HAVE TO WORK THROUGH THESE
TYPES OF THINGS.
THE DAY WILL COME WHERE WE WILL
SIT DOWN AND TRULY HIT A WALL
AND HAVE TO REALLY TALK IT OUT.
BUT IT'S WHAT THEY ARE TRAINED
TO DO AND THE MEN AND WOMEN HAVE
RISEN TO THE OCCASION AND THEY
ARE WORKING 24 HOURS A DAY AND
WILL CONTINUE WORKING UNTIL WE
RECTIFY AND ANSWER ALL OF THE
QUESTIONS AROUND WHAT HAPPENED.
>> WHICH RAISES THE QUESTION,
WHAT HAPPENED?
WHY?
HOW COULD THIS HAPPEN IN THE
MIDDLE OF CONNECTICUT IN A
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE TOWN?
I GUESS THE KEY QUESTION IS,
WHY?
DO WE HAVE AN ANSWER?
>> WE DON'T HAVE AN ANSWER YET.
WE'VE GOT A NUMBER -- A NUMBER
OF MAJOR CRIME DETECTIVES, OUR
FORENSIC PEOPLE, WE HAVE ALL OUR
EXPERTS, ALL OF OUR EXPERTISE,
WE HAVE OUR TOOLBOX WIDE OPEN
AND WE'VE GOT EVERYONE INVOLVED.
AND IT'S NOT JUST US.
WE'RE BEING ASSISTED BY THE
NEWTOWN POLICE, FEDERAL POLICE
IS HELPING US.
WE'VE GOT TO ANSWER THOSE
QUESTIONS.
WE'VE GOT TO DETERMINE HOW AND
WHY THIS HAPPENED.
WE'VE GOT TO PUT THIS PUZZLE
TOGETHER AND PAINT A CRYSTAL
CLEAR PICTURE TO TRY TO ANSWER
YOU WILL OF THE QUESTIONS
SURROUNDING THIS CASE.
>> IN YOUR MIND -- AND YOU KNOW
A LOT MORE THAN THE REST OF US,
IN YOUR MIND, DO YOU HAVE A
PRETTY GOOD IDEA WHY THIS
SHOOTER WENT INTO THE SCHOOL AND
KILLED THOSE KIDS AND TEEMPERS?
>> NOT AT ALL.
WE'RE WAY TOO EARLY AND I KNOW
THAT SOUNDS ALMOST FOUR DAYS
AFTER THE FACT BUT WE'RE WAY TOO
EARLY.
WE'VE GOT SO MUCH WORK TO DO.
SO MUCH EVIDENCE TO EXAMINE, SO
MUCH ADDITIONAL INTERVIEWS TO
CONDUCT.
IT'S GOING TO BE TIME CONSUMING
BUT WE'VE GOT TO DO ALL THAT
WORK.
LEAVE NO STONE UNTURNED.
>> WHEN YOU SAY NO INTERVIEWS, I
ASSUME YOU'RE TALKING TO HIS
FAMILY MEMBERS?
ARE THEY COOPERATING?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> AND THEY HAVE THEIR IDEAS?
>> SURE.
>> DO WE KNOW IF HE WAS UNDER
MEDICATION, IF HE HAD A MENTAL
ILLNESS, DO WE KNOW ISSUES LIKE
THAT?
>> I DON'T KNOW PERSONALLY.
I DO KNOW THE BEST WAY I CAN
EXPLAIN IT IS, WE HAVE TEAMS AND
DETECTIVES THAT WILL LOOK AT
THAT FACET.
WE'LL HAVE TEAMS AND DETECTIVES
THAT WILL LOOK AT THE WEAPONS,
THE WEAPONRY AND TRACE THEM FROM
THE MINUTE THEY CAME OFF THE
ASSEMBLY LINE UNTIL THE TIME WE
SEIZED THEM, WHO'S HANDS THEY
WERE IN.
ALL THE ANSWERS, THE AMMUNITION,
WHERE IT WAS PURCHASED, BY WHOM,
ALL OF THAT STUFF.
AND WE TRULY HAVE BOOTS ON THE
GROUND, GOOD OLD SHOE LEATHER
POLICE WORK.
MEN AND WOMEN ARE GOING TO GO
OUT THERE AND GET THESE ANSWERS.
>> IS THERE A, AS BEST AS YOU
KNOW, A SUICIDE NOTE?
>> I DO NOT KNOW.
I DO KNOW THAT WE'VE EXECUTED
SEARCH WARRANTS AT THE SECONDARY
CRIME SCENE WHICH WAS A PRIVATE
RESIDENCE.
WE DID EXTRACT A GREAT DEAL OF
EVIDENCE.
THAT I DO KNOW.
>> FROM THE HOME?
>> YES.
>> WHERE THE SHOOTER LIVED?
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
>> WITH HIS MOTHER?
BUT I DON'T HAVE A DETAILED
NOTICE OF WHAT THAT EVIDENCE IS.
I JUST KNOW THAT IT'S EXTREMELY
HELPFUL.
>> BECAUSE THE REPORTS ARE THAT
HIS COMPUTER HAD BEEN DAMAGED,
THE HARD DRIVE HAD BEEN DAMAGED
AND YOU'RE TRYING TO COME UP
WITH SOME SOEF WAITED WAY TO
COME UP WITH INFORMATION ON THAT
HARD DRIVE?
>> IT'S INTERESTING THAT THAT
INFORMATION IS OUT THERE.
THE WAY WE DO THESE TYPES OF
CASES IS, I AM THE ONLY
SPOKESMAN RELATIVE TO THIS
INVESTIGATION.
THE ONLY PERSON WHO HAS PERSONAL
KNOWLEDGE OF WHAT WE CAN AND CAN
CAN'T SAY.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHAT WAS
SEIZED IN THAT HOUSE.
THE INVESTIGATORS HAVE NOT
PROVIDED ME WITH THAT
INFORMATION BECAUSE WE DON'T
DETAIL THE EVIDENCE.
BUT SUFFICE IT TO SAY, IF THERE
WAS A COMPUTER THERE, ANY
ELECTRONIC EVIDENCE THERE, IT
WAS SEIZED.
WE HAVE A FORENSIC LABORATORY
THAT CAN ANALYZE THAT EVIDENCE.
ANY FORENSIC EVIDENCE THAT IS
WAS SEIZED AT THAT SCENE CAN GO
TO OUR SCIENTIFIC LAB.
CERTAINLY WE'LL EXAMINE IT ALL
AND HOPEFULLY IT WILL HELP US TO
A CONCLUSION.
>> IN YOUR MIND, DO YOU HAVE ANY
IDEA WHY HE KILLED HIS MOTHER?
>> I DON'T.
>> IS HIS FATHER HELPING YOU?
>> I'M SURE WE'LL TALK TO FAMILY
MEMBERS AS THIS CASE EVOLVES.
THERE'S CERTAIN STEPS AND
STRATEGIES THAT WE HAVE IN THIS
CASE, CERTAINLY THE FIRST WAS
RIGHT IN NEWTOWN ITSELF, GETTING
AS MANY ANSWERS AS WE CAN FOR
THE FAMILIES OF THESE DECEASED
VICTIMS.
ONE THING THAT WE DID DO IS WE
PROVIDED A TROOPER WITH EACH
FAMILY.
THAT HE WAS LIKE AN UMBILICAL
CORD TO AFFORD THESE VICTIMS'
FAMILIES DIRECT CONTACT TO THIS
INVESTIGATION SO THAT ANY
QUESTIONS OR ANY ISSUES THAT
THEY MIGHT HAVE, WE WOULD
CERTAINLY BE ABLE TO
INSTANTANEOUSLY GIVE THEM
ANSWERS AND HELP.
WE DIDN'T WANT THEM TO SEE, FOR
EXAMPLE, SOMETHING ON THE NEWS
ABOUT THIS CASE WITHOUT THEM
KNOWING FIRSTHAND.
WE'RE GOING TO CONTINUE TO DO
THAT.
>> 26 TROOPERS DEALING WITH 26
FAMILIES?
>> THAT'S CORRECT, SIR.
>> SO THERE'S A TROOPER ASSIGNED
TO EACH FAMILY.
HIS OLDER BROTHER, I ASSUME
YOU'RE TALKING TO HIM, HE'S
COOPERATING?
>> WE'VE REACHED OUT OVERSTATE
LINES AND HAD ASSISTANCE FROM
OUTSIDE --
>> BECAUSE HE WAS LIVING IN
HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY?
>> YES AND CERTAINLY THEY ARE
ASSISTING US WHEREVER WE
REQUIRE.
>> IT'S A TOUGH ONE.
HAVE YOU EVER HAD ANYTHING AS
TOUGH AS THIS IN YOUR CAREER?
HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN WITH THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE?
>> I JUST STARTED MY 39th YEAR
AND THIS IS THE MOST HORRIFIC
INCIDENT I'VE EVER BEEN INVOLVED
IN.
>> I WAS OVER AT THE FIREHOUSE
YESTERDAY.
I WALKED AROUND.
YOU HAD JUST LEFT.
I WAS HOPING TO MEET YOU THERE
BUT YOU HAD JUST LEFT.
YOU KNOW, WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT
WHAT WAS GOING ON INSIDE THAT
FIREHOUSE, AS THE FAMILIES WERE
GETTING THERE DOWN THE STREET
FROM THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND
WORD WAS BEGINNING TO REACH
EVERYONE THAT THERE WERE DEAD
KIDS.
>> YEP.
>> INSIDE, WHAT WAS THAT LIKE?
>> PEOPLE RESPONDED ABOUT THE
SCENE AND ABOUT THE SITUATION.
THEY RESPONDED TO COME AND
RETRIEVE THEIR CHILDREN AND WHEN
THEY COULDN'T FIND THEIR
CHILDREN, FEAR SET IN, PANIC SET
IN, PAIN SET IN.
IT WAS FEAR OF THE UNKNOWN AND
WHEN THE NOTIFICATION WAS
FINALLY MADE, IT WAS ABSOLUTELY
HEARTBREAKING.
>> YOU WERE THERE AT THE TIME?
>> YES.
>> AND THE GOVERNOR NOTIFIED THE
FAMILIES THAT THEIR LITTLE
6-YEAR-OLD OR LITTLE 7-YEAR-OLD
WAS DEAD?
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
>> WHAT WAS IT LIKE THERE?
>> IT'S SOMETHING NO ONE WANTS
TO EXPERIENCE.
IT WAS JUST HEARTBREAKING.
TERRIBLE.
>> A LOT MORE KIDS AND TEACHERS
COULD HAVE BEEN KILLED.
>> NO QUESTION.
>> THERE WAS STILL AMMUNITION HE
HAD AVAILABLE, IS THAT RIGHT?
>> THERE WAS IMMENSE AMOUNT OF
AMMUNITION AVAILABLE, YES.
>> POTENTIALLY HE COULD HAVE
KILLED --
>> HUNDREDS.
>> REALLY?
WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT THAT AND
THEN ALL OF A SUDDEN -- I GUESS
ONE OF THE MOST DIFFICULT
THINGS -- YOU WANT TO TALK TO
EYEWITNESSES BUT A LOT OF THE
EYEWITNESSES WERE KIDS.
>> THAT'S TRUE.
>> AND HOW DOES LAW ENFORCEMENT
ASK A 6, 7, 9-YEAR-OLD WHAT
HAPPENED TO BOBBY, CAROL?
>> YOU LOOK AT THE WHOLE BIG
PICTURE.
OUR INVESTIGATORS WILL MAKE A
DETERMINATION AS TO WHO NEEDS TO
BE INTERVIEWED.
SRNLY THERE WERE TWO PEOPLE THAT
WERE WOUNDED THAT SURVIVED.
>> BOTH EDUCATORS?
>> BOTH EDUCATORS.
>> HOW ARE THEY DOING?
>> WE ARE TOLD THAT THEY WILL
SURVIVE AND THEY WILL BE HUGE IN
HELPING US RECONSTRUCT THIS
EVENT.
AND WE'LL TALK TO THE EDUCATORS
IN THE FACILITY.
WE'LL TALK TO ALL OF THE
APPROPRIATE WITNESSES TO CAST
INFORMATION ON TO THIS CASE.
WE MAY OR MAY NOT TALK TO
CHILDREN.
THAT'S TO BE DETERMINED AS TO --
>> BECAUSE YOU DON'T WANT TO
AGGRAVATE -- THEY'VE GONE
THROUGH HELL TO BEGIN WITH.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
WE CANNOT AND HE WILL NOT DAMAGE
THESE CHILDREN ANY FURTHER.
THEY HAVE LIVED THROUGH HELL AND
WE'RE NOT GOING TO ADD TO THAT.
IF WE CAN GET AROUND IT, WE
WILL.
>> USUALLY WHEN YOU HAVE A MASS
SHOOTING LIKE THIS, THERE ARE A
LOT MORE INJURED THAN KILLED.
IN THIS CASE, THERE WERE 26
KILLED, TWO INJURED.
ISN'T THAT -- THAT'S PRETTY -- I
MEAN, I CAN ONLY ASSUME, HE WAS
DELIBERATELY, NOT ONLY WANTING
TO HURT, HE WANTED TO KILL.
>> THAT IS WHAT IT APPEARS.
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT IT APPEARS.
AND --
>> EACH ONE OF THESE KIDS WAS
SHOT MULTIPLE TIMES.
>> THAT'S THE MEDICAL EXAMINER'S
REPORT, YES.
AND AS I SAID, THE ROUNDS AND
HIGH-CAPACITY CLIPS THAT WERE
WITH HIM, IT COULD HAVE BEEN
MUCH WORSE.
>> STAND BY FOR MORE OF MY
INTERVIEW WITH LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE.
THAT'S COMING UP IN THE NEXT
HOUR.
WE TALK ABOUT THE EMOTIONAL TOLL
THAT THE MASSACRE INVESTIGATION
HAS HAD ON HIM AND ALL OF THE
OTHER MEN AND WOMEN IN THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE.
>>> LUS, MORE INFORMATION COMING
UP ABOUT THE INVESTIGATION.
MUCH MORE OF THE INTERVIEW IN
THE NEXT HOUR.
>>> WE ALSO HAVE GRUESOME NEW
DETAILS ABOUT THE WAY THE
GUNMAN'S MOTHER NANCY LANZA WAS
KILLED.
THE STATE MEDICAL EXAMINER
REVEALS AUTOPSY RESULTS.
>>> AND A FORMER CLASSMATE TALKS
ABOUT ADAM LANZA AND HOW HIS
MOTHER TAUGHT HIM TO USE GUNS.
>> HE STARTED GOING TO THE
SHOOTING RANGE WITH HER AND MY
RESPONSE TO THAT WAS, I NEVER
REALLY IMAGINED ADAM WANTING TO
EVER EVEN HOLD A GUN.
♪ THE WEATHER OUTSIDE
IS FRIGHTFUL ♪
♪ BUT THE FIRE IS
SO DELIGHTFUL ♪
NOTHING MELTS AWAY THE COLD
LIKE A HOT, DELICIOUS BOWL
OF CHICKEN NOODLE SOUP
FROM CAMPBELL'S.
♪ LET IT SNOW, LET IT SNOW
Meet the 5-passenger
Ford C-MAX Hybrid.
When you're carrying
a lot of weight,
C-MAX has a nice little trait,
You see, C-MAX helps
you load your freight,
with its foot-activated
lift gate.
But that's not
all you'll see,
Cause C-MAX also
beats Prius v,
with better MPG.
Say hi to the all-new 47
combined MPG C-MAX Hybrid.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>>> BIT BY BIT WE'RE LEARNING
MORE ABOUT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY GUNMAN, 20-YEAR-OLD
ADAM LANZA.
ONE OF HIS FORMER CLASSMATES
SAYS LANZA WAS ONCE, ONCE, A
GOOD KID.
QUIET, SHY, NOT THE TYPE YOU
WOULD EVER EXPECT TO COMMIT A
MASSACRE.
ALLEN DIAZ SPOKE EXCLUSIVELY TO
SUSAN CANDIOTTI.
>> HE HAD THIS TYPICAL NERD
LOOK, KHAKI PANTS, SHIRT TUCKED
IN, A COMPUTER CASE INSTEAD OF A
BACKPACK LIKE EVERYONE ELSE.
HE EVEN HAD A POCKET PROTECTOR
THAT HE HAD PENS IN.
WE ALL KIND OF KNEW LIKE THAT HE
HAD PROBLEMS SOCIALLY AND WE
KIND OF HAD A FILING THAT
FEELING THAT SOMETHING MIGHT
HAVE BEEN WRONG WITH HIM BUT WE
NEVER ASKED.
OBVIOUSLY IT DOES BECAUSE, YOU
KNOW, HE'S A VERY BIG PART OF
THIS EVENT.
I'M NOT REALLY SURE WHAT TO
THINK OF IT.
>> SADLY, HE'S THE REASON FOR
IT.
>> YEAH.
>> WE'RE GOING TO HAVE MORE OF
THAT INTERVIEW AND A REPORT FROM
SUSAN CANDIOTTI.
THAT'S COMING UP IN OUR NEXT
HOUR.
THE AUTOPSY REPORTS ON ADAM
LANZA AND HIS MOTHER NANCY ARE
PROVIDING GRUESOME NEW DETAILS
ABOUT THEIR DEATH.
WE'RE JOINED BY DEBORAH
FEYERICK.
DEB, WHAT ARE YOU LEARNING?
>> Reporter:
>> Reporter: YOU KNOW, IT REALLY
GOES TO THE HEART OF THE
INVESTIGATION INVESTIGATORS WERE
HERE FOR ABOUT AN HOUR, HOUR AND
A HALF.
THEY CONTINUE TO GATHER EVIDENCE
AND FOLLOW LEADS.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER TODAY TOLD
US THAT IN FACT NANCY LANZA WAS
SHOT IN HER BED AS SHE SLEPT
FOUR TIMES IN THE HEAD BY HER
SON.
THE COMPUTER THAT WAS RECOVERED
BY INVESTIGATORS, IT WAS CAN
COMPLETELY SMASHED.
THE HARD DRIVE SHATTERED.
THEREFORE, INVESTIGATORS ARE
HAVING A HARD TIME RETRIEVING
INFORMATION FROM THAT COMPUTER.
AND SO THE INVESTIGATOR, THE
ONLY PERSON THAT CAN COULD HAVE
POTENTIALLY TESTIFIED WHAT WAS
GOING ON IN HER SON'S MIND,
NANCY LANZ ZA WAS SHOT AND
KILLED.
YOU LOST A KEY PIECE OF EVIDENCE
AND WITNESS AS TO WHAT MAY HAVE
BEEN GOING ON.
THE BODIES OF THE ALLEGED GUNMAN
AND HIS MOM, THEY ARE NOT BEING
RELEASED JUST YET.
THEY HAVE NOT BEEN PICKED UP AND
THE FAMILY SAYS THAT THEY ARE
NOT GOING TO BE PICKED UP UNTIL
THEY ARE -- THEY ARE NOT GOING
TO BE INFORMED ABOUT THAT UNTIL
THE BODIES ARE ACTUALLY BURIED.
THEY JUST DON'T WANT TO RUN INTO
ANY KIND OF PROBLEM.
TAKE A CLOSE LISTEN, WOLF POLICE
INVESTIGATORS RETURNED TO THE
HOME OF THE GUNMAN TUESDAY.
INVESTIGATORS ARE HAVING A HARD
TIME RETRIEVING DATA FROM A BAD
DEE DAMAGED COMPUTER FOUND
INSIDE THE HOUSE, ACCORDING TO A
LAW ENFORCEMENT SOURCE, BECAUSE
THE HARD DRIVE WAS SHATTERED.
NOT ONLY DOES IT APPEAR ADAM
LANZA TRIED TO ERASE THE DIGITAL
FOOT STEPS, HE SHOT THE ONLY
WITNESS THAT COULD HAVE FULLY
EXPLAINED WHAT WAS GOING ON
INSIDE HIM.
HIS MOTHER NANCY, SHOT FOUR
TIMES IN THE HEAD AS SHE SLEPT
IN HER HEAD, LIKELY EARLY
FRIDAY, THE AUTOPSY SHOWS.
UNDER THE TERMS OF HER 2009
DIVORCE AGREEMENT, SHE WAS THE
ONE RESPONSIBLE FOR PAYING HER
SON'S PSYCHIATRIC OR
PSYCHOLOGICAL EXPENSES, PLUS
COSTS OF ANY PRESCRIPTION
MEDICATIONS NOT COVERED BY
INSURANCE.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER IS WAITING
FOR RESULTS OF TOXICOLOGY TESTS
PERFORMED ON ADAM LANZA TO SEE
IF HE WAS ON ANY MEDICATIONS OR
DRUGS THAT MAY HAVE POTENTIALLY
ADDED TO THE RAMPAGE.
THEY ARE ALSO WORKING WITH
INVESTIGATORS TO DETERMINE IF
LANZA WAS CORRECTLY DIAGNOSED
WITH AS BERGER'S OR WHETHER
ANYTHING ELSE --
>> NOW, WE ARE TOLD THAT BY A
FRIEND WHO WE SPOKE WITH LAST
NIGHT AND WHO HAD DONE WORK
INSIDE THE HOME THAT IN FACT
NANCY LANZA HAD A GUN LOCK BOX
KEPT IN THE BASEMENT OF HER
HOME.
SHE TOLD A FRIEND THAT SHE
ACTUALLY TOOK ADAM TO THE GUN
RANGE BECAUSE SHE DIDN'T WANT TO
LEAVE HIM ALONE AND THEREFORE
THEY WOULD GO TOGETHER BECAUSE
SHE WAS WORRIED ABOUT HIM.
WHAT'S SO INTERESTING, WOLF,
ABOUT THREE YEARS AGO, BACK IN
2009, THAT'S REALLY THE LAST
TIME WE HAVE ANY HARD RECORD OF
ANY CLASSES HE TOOK, ANY COURSES
HE WAS ENROLLED IN.
AFTER THAT, RIGHT AT THE TIME
THAT THE DIVORCE WAS FINALIZED,
IT SEEMS AS IF ADAM LANZA FELL
OFF THE FACE OF THE EARTH.
THERE'S NO RECORD OF WHAT HE
DID, WHO HE MET WITH.
WE'VE HAD A VERY DIFFICULT TIME
FINDING FRIENDS WHO KNEW HIM
FROM THE PERIOD 2009 ON.
SO HE EXISTED BUT HE EXISTED IN
A WORLD THAT REALLY NOBODY KNOWS
ABOUT, WOLF.
>> DEBORAH FEYERICK, THANKS VERY
MUCH FOR THAT REPORT.
LET'S DIG A LITTLE DEEPER.
KATE BOLDUAN IS JOINING US HERE
IN NEWTOWN AS WE'VE PUT THE
LATEST INFORMATION OF ADAM
LANZA'S MENTALITY HEALTH INTO A
PROPER PERSPECTIVE.
JOINING US IS DR. DREW.
DR. DREW, THE MEDICAL EXAMINER
SAYS HE WAS TOLD THAT ADAM LANZA
HAD BEEN DIAGNOSED WITH
ASBERGER'S SYNDROME.
WHAT DOES THAT HAVE TO DO WITH
VIOLENCE BECAUSE AS FAR AS I
KNOW THAT HAS NOTHING TO DO WITH
VIOLENT BEHAVIOR.
YOU'RE A PSYCHIATRIST.
>> I DO DEAL WITH THIS A LOT.
IT'S A NEUROBIOLOGICAL, AND NOT
THOUGHT OF AS A MENTAL DISORDER
PER SE.
ONE OF THE CHARACTERISTICS IS
NOT PICKING UP ON SOCIAL CUES,
SOMETIMES SO SEVERELY THAT THEY
HAVE DIFFICULTY EMPHASIZING WITH
PEOPLE BUT CATEGORICALLY IS NOT
ASSOCIATED WITH VIOLENCE UNTIL
THERE ARE OTHER THINGS GOING ON.
YOU HAVE TO WONDER WHAT THE
SECOND HIT WAS HERE THAT CAUSED
HIM TO RETREAT SO SEVERELY TO
THE POINT THAT HE WAS IN THE
HOME, ISOLATED, AND A YOUNG
ADULT UNABLE TO BE LEFT ALONE BY
HIS MOTHER TO THE POINT THAT SHE
TAKES HIM TO THE SHOOTING RANGE,
THAT'S BIZARRE.
BY THE WAY, MOM IS GOING TO PLAY
A BIG ROLE HERE.
THERE IS NOT A MENTAL HEALTH
PROFESSIONAL THAT WOULD SAY TO
TAKE TO A SHOOTING RANGE TO
ENHANCE HIS SELF-ESTEEM.
THERE'S SOMETHING GOING ON HERE
WITH MOM AS WELL.
WE'RE GOING TO FIND OUT.
>> YEAH, I THINK YOU'RE
ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
BUT WHAT MEDICATION NORMALLY
WOULD BE ASSOCIATED WITH
ASPERGER'S SYNDROME?
BECAUSE WE HEARD SANJAY GUPTA,
SENSITIVE MEDICATION, WHEN YOU
GO OFF OF IT, THAT COULD CAUSE
SOME PROBLEMS.
>> IT CAUSES TROUBLE BUT NOT
PREMEDITATED VIOLENCE.
IT CAN CAUSE AGITATION AND
EXTREME FLUCTUATIONS OF MOOD BUT
THIS IS UNLIKELY TO BE SOMETHING
SPECIFICALLY RELATED TO
MEDICATION.
ASPERGER'S MEDICATION, NO, NOT
TYPICALLY.
SOMETIMES THERE'S SOMETHING
CALLED CHEMICAL CONTAINMENT TO
HELP PEOPLE CONTAIN FOCUS, BEING
ABLE TO MANAGE BETTER.
YES, THE SEVERELY AUTISTIC
SPECTRUM SOMETIMES GETS INTO
THOSE MEDICATIONS AND YOU HAVE
TO WONDER WHETHER THIS IS
FURTHER DOWN THE AUTISTIC
SYNDROME.
AND BY THE WAY, THESE WORDS LIKE
ASPERGER'S ARE GOING TO ALMOST
HAVE NO MEANING GOING FORWARD.
THERE IS SOMETHING THAT IS
REALLY TROUBLING ME.
WE ARE BEING HELD HOSTAGE BY
PRIVACY ISSUES.
SO MANY PEOPLE ARE TALKING ABOUT
THE INABILITY TO ENROLL NATIONAL
GUN LAWS BECAUSE OF FEAR OF
SUITS BY THE LEGAL SYSTEM FOR,
GOD FORBID, ANYBODY ASKING
QUESTIONS ABOUT SOMEBODY'S
PREVIOUS HISTORY IF THEY WANT TO
HAVE A WEAPON.
AND I THINK THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
IT'S WHY WE HAVE PROBLEMS LIKE
THIS.
IT'S WHY DOCTORS CAN'T DO THEIR
JOBS AND WHY PARENT ARE STUCK
WITH KIDS LIKE THIS AT HOME AND
WHY WE CAN'T GET ACTION ON GUN
LAWS.
>> AND DR. DREW, WHEN YOU'RE
LOOKING AT ADAM LANZA, WHAT IN
HIS MEDICAL HISTORY DO YOU THINK
INVESTIGATORS SHOULD BE FOCUSING
MORE ON?
WHAT ARE THEY LOOKING INTO TO
PAINT A MORE COMPLETE PICTURE OF
THE PERSON THAT WE ARE TALKING
ABOUT?
AND WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT -- AND
WHAT ABOUT THE TOXICOLOGY
REPORT?
WHAT SHOULD THEY BE LOOKING AT
WHEN THAT COMES IN?
>> THAT IS ABSOLUTELY CORRECT.
I THINK THE TWO AREAS THAT ARE
GOING TO GIVE US THE MOST
INFORMATION IS HIS LIFE ONLINE
BECAUSE VERY OFTEN PEOPLE THAT
HAVE ARE DIFFICULTY WITH
INTIMATE CONNECTION WITH OTHERS,
THEY HAVE QUITE A RICH LIFE OUT
THERE IN THE CYBERSPACE AND IT
CAN BE BIZARRE AND THEY CAN FUEL
SOME OF THESE HORRIBLE SORTS OF
PREOCCUPATIONS AND VIOLENT
TENDENCIES.
IT DOESN'T CAUSE THEM BUT THE
ONLINE LIFE IS GOING TO BE VERY
REVEALING AND FOR SURE THE TOX
KOLGS ARE GOING TO BE CRITICAL.
THERE'S TWO BIG QUESTIONS HERE.
DID SOMEHOW THE MEDICATION
EITHER COMING ON OR GOING OFF,
MAYBE HE WAS PRESCRIBED
MEDICATION AND DIDN'T TAKE IT.
WE'RE GOING TO FIND A LACK OF
MEDICATION IN HIS SYSTEM OR, GOD
FORBID, HE GOT ON TO SOME
ILLICIT SUBSTANCES, LIKE A
METHAMPHETAMINE AND THAT COULD
EASILY EXPLAIN HOW SOMEBODY
COULD FLIP INTO THIS KIND OF AN
AGITATED STATE.
>> AND LOOKING FORWARD FOR THE
COMMUNITY HERE, WE KNOW SOME
STUDENTS ARE HEADING BACK TO
SCHOOL.
WE HEARD SOME PARENTS HOW
DIFFICULT IT IS IS FOR THE KIDS
TO BE HEADING BACK TO SCHOOL.
THE YOUNG CHILDREN AT SANDY
HOOK, THEY ARE NOT GOING TO BE
STARTING BACK TO CLASS UNTIL
AFTER THE HOLIDAY BREAK IN
JANUARY.
FROM YOUR PERSPECTIVE, WHEN DO
YOU THINK IT IS THE RIGHT TIME
FOR CHILDREN TO BE GOING BACK TO
CLASS AFTER THEY'VE EXPERIENCED
SUCH TRAUMA AT SCHOOL?
>> YEAH: TO COME EXTENT, WE HAVE
TO KIND OF LEAVE IT UP TO THE
KIDS A LITTLE BIT.
IF THEY REALLY FEEL
UNCOMFORTABLE LEAVING THE HOME
AND WANT TO STAY WITH THEIR
FAMILY, THAT'S WHAT THEY SHOULD
DO.
I DEFINITELY THINK HOLIDAY AT
HOME WITH THEIR FAMILY, SAFETY,
NORMALCY BACK IN THEIR LIFE,
THERE IS IS QUESTION WHETHER
THEY SHOULD GO BACK INTO THAT
PARTICULAR ENVIRONMENT WHERE
THAT HAPPENED.
SOME KIDS MAY WANT TO DO THAT TO
REGAIN A MASTER REE WHAT
HAPPENED TO THEM.
OTHERS MAY BE MORTIFIED AND
TRIGGERED BY IT AND SHOULD NOT
BE FORCED TO DO SO.
ULTIMATELY EACH CHILD IS GOING
TO DEAL WITH IT DIFFERENTLY.
TRAUMA AND GRIEF ARE CHAOTIC
EXPERIENCES.
EACH OF US OUT THERE, I
CHALLENGE ANY ONE OF YOU WHO HAS
BEEN WATCHING THIS STORY NOT TO
AGREE WITH ME THAT THE FEELINGS
THAT WASH OVER US ARE CHAOTIC
AND UNPREDICTABLE AND RANGE FROM
RAGE TO MISERY TO SADNESS TO
DISGUST AND THAT'S NORMAL.
THESE THINGS ARE GOING TO
CONTINUE TO RUSH OVER US FOR
WEEKS TO COME AND IT'S INCUMBENT
UPON US TO TAKE ACTION, SERVICE
WILL HELP US, CREATE SOME
CONCEPT OF FAITH, WHATEVER THAT
CONCEPT IS FOR YOU AND THEN
FINALLY CONNECT WITH PEOPLE THAT
LOVE YOU AND KNOW YOU.
STAY WITH THEM AND STAY CLOSE TO
THEM.
>> DR. DREW, WHAT SHOULD PARENTS
BE LOOKING FOR RIGHT NOW?
BECAUSE SOMETIMES TRAUMA --
POSTTRAUMATIC STRESS DISORDER,
THAT TAKES A WHILE TO GO INTO
EFFECT.
WHAT ARE THE SIGNS THAT PARENTS
SHOULD BE LOOKING AT WITH THEIR
KIDS RIGHT NOW?
>> YEAH.
LISTEN, ALL OF US -- AND
PARTICULARLY THOSE IN PROXIMITY
TO THE TRAUMA -- ARE GOING TO
HAVE AN ACUTE STRESS REACTION
AND THAT IS NORMAL.
I DON'T KNOW HOW MANY OF YOUR
VIEWERS NOTICE YOU'RE NOT
SLEEPING RIGHT, YOU'RE
PREOCCUPIED SLEEPING ABOUT THIS
THING.
YOU MAY HAVE CHAOTIC FEELINGS
THAT COME OVER YOU.
YOU MAY HAVE PANIC IF YOU'RE
PREDISPOSED TO THAT.
THIS IS THE TIME TO INTERVENE,
RIGHT NOW, SO THIS DOES NOT
PROGRESS TO A POSTTRAUMATIC
STRESS DISORDER WHICH IS AN
ONGOING PERSISTENT DISORDER THAT
HAS A DIFFERENT SET OF
SYMPTOMATOLOGY AND TREATMENT
ASSOCIATED WITH IT.
KIDS MAY REGRESS, THE YOUNGER
KIDS MAY RETURN TO THINGS LIKE
WETTING THEIR BED, THEY MAY
WITHDRAW, MAY BE AGITATED, MAY
HAVE A CHANGE IN THEIR EATING
HABITS.
THE ONE CAVEAT THAT I GIVE TO
PARENTS DO NOT EXPECT YOUR KIDS
TO TALK ABOUT THIS AND PROCESS.
KIDS TRY TO PAK SENSE OF THINGS
IN THEIR OWN WAY.
LET THEM GO ABOUT IT THEIR OWN
WAY.
I HEARD A BEAUTIFUL WAY OF
CONCEPTUALIZING, THAT GOD NEEDED
SOME WONDERFUL ANGELS AND HE
CALLED FOR THEM AND HE HAS THIS
LOVELY GROUP OF ANGELS WITH
THEM.
HE NEEDED THEM, HE ASKED FOR
THEM, AND HE GOT THEM.
AND THAT CHILD WAS GIVEN A GIFT,
A WAY TO CONCEPTUALIZE AND
UNDERSTAND SOMETHING THAT IS
FRANKLY NOT ABLE TO BE
UNDERSTOOD IN ANY RATIONAL WAY
BECAUSE THIS WAS A COMPLETELY
IRRATIONAL ACT.
>> DR. DREW, EXCELLENT,
EXCELLENT ADVICE.
WE REALLY APPRECIATE IT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR JOINING
US.
>> THANK YOU, GUYS.
APPRECIATE IT.
MY PLEASURE.
>>> AND PLEASE BE SURE TO WATCH
DR. DREW ON CALL, WEEK NIGHTS AT
9:00 P.M. ON OUR SISTER STATION
HLN.
>>> THERE'S OTHER NEWS HAPPENING
IN "THE SITUATION ROOM,"
INCLUDING NEWTOWN BEGINNING THE
GRIM BUSINESS OF BURYING THE
CHILDREN WHOSE LIVES ENDED FAR
TOO SOON.
Like a lot of things,
trying to find a better job can
be frustrating.
So at University of Phoenix
we're working with a growing
list of almost two thousand
corporate partners -
companies like Microsoft,
American Red Cross and Adobe -
to create options for you.
Not only that, we're using what
we learn from these partners
to shape our curriculum, so that
when you find the job you want
you'll be a perfect fit.
Let's get to work.
>>> THE NATIONAL RIFLE
ASSOCIATION HAS JUST RELEASED
ITS FIRST PUBLIC STATEMENT SINCE
THE KILLING THERE IN NEWTOWN ON
FRIDAY MORNING.
I'LL READ IT TO OUR VIEWERS FROM
THE NRA.
THE NRA IS MADE UP OF FOUR
MILLION MOMS AND DADS, BE SONS
AND DAUGHTERS, AND WE WERE
SHOCKED, SADDENED, AND
HEARTBROKEN BY THE NEWS OF THE
HORRIFIC AND SENSELESS MURDERS
IN NEWTOWN.
OUT OF RESPECT FOR THE FAMILIES
AND AS A MATTER OF COMMON
DECENCY, WE HAVE GIVEN TIME FOR
A MOURNING, PRAYER AND FULL
INVESTIGATION OF THES BEFORE
COMMENTING.
THE NRA IS PREPARED TO OFFER
MEANINGFUL CONTRIBUTIONS TO HELP
MAKE SURE THAT THIS NEVER
HAPPENS.
THAT'S THE FIRST PUBLIC
STATEMENT SINCE THE KILLINGS
HERE IN NEWTOWN FRIDAY MORNING.
THE NRA ALSO SAYS IT WILL HOLD A
MAJOR NEWS CONFERENCE THIS
COMING FRIDAY, DECEMBER 21st, IN
WASHINGTON, D.C.
OF COURSE, WE'LL COVER THAT AS
WELL.
>>> THERE HAS BEEN ANOTHER
DEADLY SHOOTING IN COLORADO.
POLICE SAY FOUR PEOPLE ARE DEAD
IN A MURDER-SUICIDE.
LISA SYLVESTER IS MONITORING
THAT.
WHAT DO YOU HAVE, LISA?
>> WOLF, IT'S A DISTURBING STORY
OF A WOMAN'S 911 STRATEGY.
IT HAPPENED IN COLORADO.
AUTHORITIES SAY AS THE CALL FOR
HELP CAME IN, A DISPATCHER HEARD
GUNSHOTS, A MAN SAYING HE WAS
GOING TO KILL HIMSELF, AND THEN
ANOTHER GUNSHOT.
A S.W.A.T. TEAM LATER FOUND TWO
MEN AND TWO WOMEN DEAD AT THE
SCENE.
AT AN NBC TEAM KIDNAPPED IN
SYRIA IS FREE AND UNHARMED AND
EXPRESSING RELIEF TODAY.
RICHARD ENGEL SAYS HIS CREW WAS
CAPTURED LAST WEEK AS THEY
CROSSED FROM TURKEY INTO SYRIA.
HE BELIEVES HIS KIDNAPPERS WERE
MILITIA LOYAL TO THE SYRIAN
GOVERNMENT.
>>> THE AVERAGE PRICE OF REGULAR
SELF-SERVE GASOLINE IN THE U.S.
IS NOW $3.24.
THE PRICE HAS FALLEN EVERY DAY
FOR ALMOST A MONTH AND IT COULD
FALL TO LEVELS NOT SEEN IN TWO
YEARS.
ANALYSTS CREDIT IN PART THE
BETTER ECONOMY AND CONTINUED
HIGH UNEMPLOYMENT.
WOLF?
>> LISA, THANK YOU.
>>> TWO MORE FAMILIES HERE IN
CONNECTICUT BURYING THEIR
CHILDREN.
THEIR FUNERALS AND THEIR
STORIES.
THAT'S AHEAD.
COPD INCLUDES CHRONIC
BRONCHITIS AND EMPHYSEMA.
SPIRIVA HELPS CONTROL
MY COPD SYMPTOMS
BY KEEPING MY AIRWAYS
OPEN FOR 24 HOURS.
PLUS, IT REDUCES COPD FLARE-UPS.
SPIRIVA IS THE ONLY ONCE-DAILY
INHALED COPD MAINTENANCE
TREATMENT THAT DOES BOTH.
SPIRIVA HANDIHALER TIOTROPIUM
BROMIDE INHALATION POWDER
DOES NOT REPLACE FAST-ACTING
INHALERS FOR SUDDEN SYMPTOMS.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU HAVE
KIDNEY PROBLEMS, GLAUCOMA,
TROUBLE URINATING, OR
AN ENLARGED PROSTATE.
THESE MAY WORSEN WITH SPIRIVA.
DISCUSS ALL MEDICINES
YOU TAKE, EVEN EYE DROPS.
STOP TAKING SPIRIVA AND SEEK
IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
IF YOUR BREATHING
SUDDENLY WORSENS,
YOUR THROAT OR TONGUE
SWELLS, YOU GET HIVES,
VISION CHANGES OR EYE PAIN,
OR PROBLEMS PASSING URINE.
FOR ALMOST A MONTH AND IT COULD
THEIR FUNERALS AND THEIR
NOTHING CAN REVERSE COPD.
SPIRIVA HELPS ME BREATHE BETTER.
(BLOWING SOUND)
ASK YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT SPIRIVA.
FOR ALMOST A MONTH AND IT COULD
THEIR FUNERALS AND THEIR
>>> A GIRL WHO LOVED HORSES AND
A BOY WHO LOVED TO SWIM, THURP
BURIED HERE IN NEWTOWN.
JESSICA REKOS AND JAM MAT YOLLY,
THEY WERE BOTH 6 YEARS OLD.
CNN'S DON LEMON IS JOINING US
HERE IN NEWTOWN.
HOW SAD IS THIS, DON, BECAUSE
YOU WERE SPEAKING TO A LOT OF
PEOPLE IN THIS WONDERFUL
COMMUNITY.
>> IT'S REALLY SAD.
THE ONE GOOD THING THAT IS
COMING OUT OF THIS IS THAT
PEOPLE ARE COMING TOGETHER AND
PEOPLE ARE SHOWING US THEIR
SUPPORT.
YOU CAN SEE HOW HIGH THE STUFFED
ANIMALS AND FLOWERS, BE IT'S ALL
PACKED IN HERE.
PEOPLE PUT UP A CROSS AND
CHRISTMAS TREES AND A ROCKING
HORSE.
WOLF, LET'S LEARN A LITTLE BIT
MORE ABOUT THE 6-YEAR-OLDS WHO
LOVED LIFE SO MUCH.
THE FIRST ONE IS JAMES MATTIOLI.
HE WAS 6 YEARS OLD AND WAS
JUMPED TO AS JAY.
HE WAS A FAN OF WRESTLING, THAT
HE LIKED MATH AND HAIR GEL AND
HE WAS IN LOVE WITH HIS BIG
SISTER ANNA.
HE WOULD OFTEN SING AT THE TOP
OF HIS LUNGS AND LOVED THE
OUTDOORS.
HE LOVED DIVING INTO POOL,
RIDING HIS BICYCLE AND HE WAS
PROUD THAT HE DIDN'T NEED
TRAINING WHEELS AND WE CAN ALL
REMEMBER WHEN WE WERE THAT AGE
AND ONCE YOU DIDN'T NEED
TRAINING WHEELS, WE WERE ALL
LITTLE TYKES THEM.
ALSO, JESSICA REKOS WAS KNOWN AS
THE CEO OF HER FAMILY.
THEY CALLED HER THE BOSS.
SHE RULED THE ROOST.
SHE WAS A BALL OF FIRE AND A
PLANNER AND HER FAMILY PROMISED
HER SHE WOULD GET A HORSE BY THE
TIME SHE TURNED 10.
BUT THIS CHRISTMAS, ACCORDING TO
HER MOTHER, SHE WAS LOOKING
FORWARD TO GETTING A PAIR OF
COULD YOU GIRL BOOTS.
THIS IS HOW HER MOTHER TALKED
ABOUT IT.
>> IT'S STILL NOT REAL THAT MY
LITTLE GIRL WHO WAS SO FULL OF
LIFE AND WHO WANTS A HORSE SO
BADLY AND WHO WAS GOING TO GET
COWGIRL BOOTS FOR CHRISTMAS
ISN'T COMING HOME.
>> AND OF COURSE, THAT'S THE
MOM.
THE MOM'S NAME IS CHRISTINA.
I CAN'T IMAGINE HOW SHE WAS EVEN
ABLE TO GARNER THE STRENGTH TO
DO THAT INTERVIEW.
BUT, AGAIN, THERE ARE PEOPLE NOW
YOU SEE HERE WHO ARE PAYING
THEIR TRIBUTES IN THEIR OWN WAY,
PEOPLE WHO MAY NOT HAVE BEEN
ABLE TO GO TO THE FUNERAL TODAY,
THEY ARE DROPPING OFF FLOWERS
AND COMING HERE JUST TO CONSOLE
EACH OTHER AND THIS MEMORIAL,
THIS IS JUST ONE OF THEM, WOLF,
THAT YOU AND I HAVE SEEN.
ONE OF THEM THAT IS JUST
GROWING.
YOU CAN FEEL THE LOVE OUT HERE
AND YOU CAN FEEL THAT PEOPLE
WANT TO COME HERE JUST TO SHOW
THEIR SUPPORT AND TO REALLY HUG
EACH OTHER.
EVERY SINGLE PERSON WHO HAS BEEN
COMING UP TO US HAS BEEN WANTING
TO HUG US SAYING THAT, YOU KNOW,
WE'RE GLAD YOU GUYS ARE HERE.
USUALLY WHEN THE MEDIA COMES TO
TOWN WE'RE NOT SO HAPPY TO SEE
THE MEDIA BUT WE'RE GLAD THAT
YOU'RE HERE AND SHOWING THE
WORLD THAT THIS COMMUNITY IS NOT
GOING TO BE REMEMBERED FOR A
TRAGIC EVENT BUT REMEMBERED FOR
THE LOVE THAT THEY SHOWED EACH
OTHER AND ARE ESPECIALLY SHOWING
EACH OTHER IN THIS MEMORIAL THAT
THEY'VE ERECTED IN THE MIDDLE OF
NEWTOWN.
>> DON, YOU'VE DEFINITELY BEEN
SPEAKING TO A LOT OF PEOPLE FROM
THE TOWN AND MANY PEOPLE COMING
IN FROM OUT OF TOWN TO SHOW
THEIR SUPPORT.
WHAT ARE YOU HEARING FROM FOLKS
ABOUT WHERE THINGS GO FROM HERE,
OR EVEN IN THE SHORT TERM BEING
WHAT THE NEXT TWO WEEKS LOOKS
LIKE.
>> YOU KNOW WHAT, THEY DON'T
KNOW.
OF COURSE, TWO MORE TODAY AND
THEY SAY RIGHT NOW IT'S DAY BY
DAY BY DAY AND AS WE HAVE BEEN
OUT HERE TALKING TO PEOPLE AND
THEY HAVE BEEN COMING HERE, SOME
OF THE PROCESSIONS -- ONE OF THE
PROCESSIONS CAME BY TODAY AND
YOU COULD SEE THE PEOPLE IN THAT
PROCESSION.
YOU COULD SEE THE HERSES AND THE
MOVING TRUCKS, YOU AND I SAW
THAT, THEY WERE MOVING THE
THINGS FROM THIS SCHOOL TO THE
OTHER SCHOOL WHERE IT'S GOING TO
BE TEMPORARILY.
THEY PASSED EACH OTHER AND IT
WAS QUITE A THING TO SEE ONE
THING MOVING ON AND THE OTHER
THING, THE PARENTS AND FAMILY
MEMBERS AND LOVED ONES GOING TO
LAY THEIR LITTLE LOVED ONES TO
REST.
IT WAS -- IT WAS JUST
UNBELIEVABLE TO SEE.
I DON'T EVEN HAVE THE WORDS FOR
IT, KATE.
>> SO HEARTBREAKING FOR ALL OF
US.
DON IS GOING TO BE BACK IN THE
NEXT HOUR.
WE'RE GOING TO CONTINUE THIS
CONVERSATION.
HERE'S THE QUESTION.
IS THE WHITE HOUSE READY TO GET
SERIOUS ABOUT GUN CONTROL?
IF SO, THE WHITE HOUSE PRESS
SECRETARY TODAY GAVE US A LITTLE
BIT OF AN IDEA ABOUT HOW THE
PRESIDENT IS GOING TO RESPOND.
STAND BY.
ASKS WHAT IT FEELS
TO DRIVE A JEEP GRAND CHEROKEE,
TELL THEM
IT'S LIKE BEING NESTLED
IN AN EIGHT-WAY, ADJUSTABLE,
HEATED AND VENTILATED SEAT
SURROUNDED BY A 500-WATT
SOUND SYSTEM
WHILE FLOATING ON A SUSPENSION
MADE OF BILLOWY CLOUDS.
OR YOU COULD JUST HAND THEM
YOUR KEYS.
♪
>>> BEFORE FRIDAY'S APPALLING
GUN VIOLENCE, GUN CONTROL WAS
ALMOST ON NOBODY'S AGENDA IN
WASHINGTON BUT NOW IT HAS BECOME
A PRIORITY FOR MANY LAWMAKERS.
BRIANNA KEILAR IS JOINING US
WITH MORE ON THIS DEBATE.
WHERE IS IT HEADING, BRIANNA?
>> Reporter: WOLF, IT'S HEATING
UP.
THE NRA IS HAVING A PRESS
CONFERENCE TOMORROW.
THAT'S ALSO A SIGN THAT THIS
DEBATE IS HEATING UP AND IT'S NO
COINCIDENCE THAT THAT COMES ON
THE HEELS OF THE WHITE HOUSE
DETAILING SOME OF THE STEPS IT
WANTS TO TAKE ON GUN VIOLENCE.
TODAY, FOR THE FIRST TIME, THE
WHITE HOUSE GOT SPECIFIC ON HOW
THE PRESIDENT WILL TACKLE GUN
VIOLENCE.
>> IS HE ACTIVELY CONSIDERING
MEASURES, BE IT GUN LAWS OR
MENTAL HEALTH MEASURES RIGHT
NOW?
>> WELL, HE IS ACTIVELY
SUPPORTIVE OF, FOR EXAMPLE,
SENATOR FEINSTEIN'S STATED
INTENT TO REVIVE A PIECE OF
LEGISLATION THAT WOULD REINSTATE
THE ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN.
>> Reporter: THE WHITE HOUSE
SAYS THE PRESIDENT WOULD LIKE TO
CLOSE THE GUN LOOPHOLE AND LOOK
AT MEASURES THAT ADDRESS MENTAL
HEALTH.
CRITICS HAVE SAID THAT THE
PRESIDENT HAS NOT LED ON GUN
RIGHTS AND THEY SAY IT'S TIME TO
FIND A BIPARTISAN SOLUTION.
>> I THINK MOST REPUBLICANS ARE
WILLING TO HAVE A VERY SERIOUS
CONVERSATION AND FIND OUT WHAT
THE SECOND MEANS IN THE 21st
CENTURY.
>> I THINK YOU'RE TRYING TO TURN
THIS INTO A POLITICAL THEATER
THING.
>> Reporter: BUT THE PRESIDENT
IS APPEARING TO ACT MORE
AGGRESSIVELY ON THE ISSUE.
HE CALLED WEST VIRGINIA SENATOR
JOE MANCHIN, A PRO-GUN RIGHTS
DEMOCRAT WHO ONCE STARTED HIS
OWN CAMPAIGN AD PUSHED BY
PRESIDENT OBAMA.
HE SAYS IT'S TIME TO ACT ON
VIOLENCE.
THE PRESIDENT MET WITH VICE
PRESIDENT JOE BIDEN, ARNIE
DUNCAN, KATHLEEN SEBELIUS, AND
ATTORNEY GENERAL ERIC HOLDER.
A DEMONSTRATION OF THE
COMPREHENSIVE APPROACH THE
PRESIDENT WANTS TO TAKE IN
COMBATTING THE PROBLEM.
OBSERVERS OF THIS DEBATE ALSO
SAY PRESIDENT OBAMA COULD EXERT
HIS EXECUTIVE AUTHORITY TO
BYPASS CONGRESS AND DO SOME
THINGS ON HIS OWN.
THAT COULD INCLUDE SHARE
INFORMATION, A BETTER SHARING OF
INFORMATION BETWEEN FEDERAL,
STATE, AND LOCAL LAW
ENFORCEMENTS ABOUT POTENTIAL
ILLEGAL GUN PURCHASES.
I MENTIONED WE TALKED ABOUT THAT
GUN CONFERENCE.
THAT WAS ON FRIDAY, NOT
TOMORROW.
I MISSPOKE.
>> THEY JUST ISSUED A STATEMENT,
BRIANNA.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THAT GUN CONTROL DEBATE IS ABOUT
TO INTEN FI BIG TIME IN
WASHINGTON.
>>> THE FOUNDING FATHERS HAD NO
IDEA THAT THEY WERE KICKING A
HORNET'S NEST BY GUARANTEEING
AMERICANS THE RIGHT TO BEAR
ARMS.
THEY STARTED A FIERCE DEBATE
THAT GOES ON TODAY.
WE'RE GOING TO TALK ABOUT THE
LEGAL RAMIFICATIONS COMING UP
WITH JEFFREY TOOBIN.
>>> ALSO, ADAM LANZA HAS BEEN
DESCRIBED AS A LONER AND ONE MAN
IS DESCRIBING ABOUT THIS MAN
THAT CARRIED OUT THIS HORRIFIC
RAMPAGE.
I ALWAYS WAIT
UNTIL THE LAST MINUTE.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME FOR CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
♪
BECOMING
PART OF THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
TREES WILL TALK TO NETWORKS
WILL TALK TO SCIENTISTS
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE.
CARS WILL TALK TO ROAD SENSORS
WILL TALK TO STOPLIGHTS
ABOUT TRAFFIC EFFICIENCY.
THE AMBULANCE WILL TALK
TO PATIENT RECORDS
WILL TALK TO DOCTORS
ABOUT SAVING LIVES.
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
THE NEXT BIG THING?
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
♪
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
♪
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
>>> THERE MAY BE NO MORE
CONSTITUTIONAL COULDN'T VERSE
YEE THAN THE RIGHT TO BEAR ARMS
AND THE DEVIL IS IN THE DETAILS
AND FOR DECADES AMERICANS HAVE
ARGUED WHICH ARMS WE SHOULD BE
ALLOWED TO BEAR.
JEFFREY TOOBIN IS AUTHOR OF "THE
OATH" AND SENIOR LEGAL ANALYST.
HE'S JOINING US FROM NEW YORK.
HERE'S WHAT THE CONSTITUTION,
THE SECOND AMENDMENT SAYS, YOU
KNOW THIS WELL.
A WELL REGULATED MILITIA BEING
NECESSARY TO THE SECURITY OF A
FREE STATE, THE RIGHT OF THE
PEOPLE TO KEEP AND BEAR ARMS
SHALL NOT BE INFRINGED.
OVER THE YEARS, AS YOU WELL
KNOW, JEFFREY, THIS HAS GONE
THROUGH A LOT OF
INTERPRETATIONS.
MOST RECENTLY IN 2008.
>> VERY DRAMATICALLY DIFFERENT
INTERPRETATIONS.
BEFORE 2008, FOR 100 YEARS, THAT
FIRST CLAUSE, THE SO-CALLED
MILITIA CLAUSE, WAS READ BY THE
SUPREME COURT AND OTHER COURTS
TO TRUMP THE RIGHT TO KEEP AND
BEAR ARMS.
THAT AMENDMENT WAS INTERPRETED
FOR DECADES AS GIVING
INDIVIDUALS NO RIGHT TO KEEP AND
BEAR ARMS.
IN 2008, THAT CHANGED ON A DIME.
THE UNITED STATES SUPREME COURT
IN A DECISION CALLED HELLAR SAID
THAT THE SECOND AMENDMENT GIVES
INDIVIDUALS THE RIGHT TO KEEP
AND BEAR ARMS BUT WHAT ARMS,
WHERE YOU GET TO KEEP THEM,
THAT'S STILL VERY MUCH UP FOR
GRABS.
>> SO WHAT RESTRICTS ARE LEGAL?
>> WELL, LET'S START WITH WHAT
RESTRICTS WE KNOW ARE ILLEGAL.
IT IS ILLEGAL NOW FOR A
GOVERNMENT, A LOCAL GOVERNMENT
OR THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT TO BAN
THE POSSESSION OF HANDGUNS
WITHIN THE HOME.
THAT IS WHAT THE HELLER CASE WAS
ABOUT.
THE GOVERNMENT CAN'T DO THAT.
BUT IT STARTS TO GET MURKIER
WHEN IT'S ABOUT OTHER WEAPONS
THAN HANDGUNS AND OUTSIDE THE
HOME.
IT SEEMS PRETTY CLEAR THAT
AUTOMATIC WEAPONS, SEMIAUTOMATIC
WEAPONS, ASSAULT RIFLES, THOSE
CAN BE REGULATED.
THE ISSUE OF WHETHER THEY CAN BE
REGULATED IN TERMS OF CAN YOU
HAVE CONCEALED, CARRY THEM IN A
CONCEALED WAY OR CARRY THEM
OPENLY IS ALSO AN OPEN QUESTION.
BUT THIS IS AN AREA OF WHERE THE
LAW IS CHANGING A LOT AND TENDS
TO BE MOVING IN THE DIRECTION OF
LESS REGULATION OF FIREARMS.
SO THAT'S SOMETHING CONGRESS IS
GOING TO HAVE TO THINK ABOUT IF
AND WHEN IT DECIDES TO PASS ANY
LAW.
>> JEFFREY, LISTEN TO WHAT DR.
DREW PINSKY JUST TOLD ME THIS
HOUR HERE IN "THE SITUATION
ROOM."
I'LL PLAY THE CLIP AND THEN
WE'LL DISCUSS.
>> SO MUCH OF WHAT PEOPLE ARE
TALKING ABOUT IS THE INABILITY
TO ENROLL RATIONAL GUN LAWS
BECAUSE OF FEAR OF SUITS BY THE
LEGAL SYSTEM FOR GOD FORBID
ANYBODY ASKING QUESTIONS ABOUT
SOMEBODY'S PREVIOUS HISTORY IF
THEY WANT TO HAVE A WEAPON.
AND I THINK THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
>> SO ARE PRIVACY LAWS PART OF
THIS PROBLEM, AS HE'S
SUGGESTING?
>> I THINK WHAT DREW IS SAYING
IS THAT THE NRA AND OTHER GROUPS
THAT OPPOSE REGULATION AND
REGISTRATION OF GUNS, THEY ARE
SAYING, YOU KNOW, YOU CAN'T
INVADE PEOPLE'S PRIVACY BY
ASKING THEM QUESTIONS ABOUT, DO
THEY HAVE A MENTAL HEALTH
HISTORY, DO THEY HAVE A CRIMINAL
RECORD?
AND, YOU KNOW, THAT IS AN
OBJECTION THAT HAS BEEN RAISED.
I DON'T THINK IT'S
CONSTITUTIONALLY SIGNIFICANT.
BUT IT MIGHT BE POLITICALLY
SIGNIFICANT.
YOU KNOW, GUN OWNERS ARE A VERY
POWERFUL GROUP IN THIS COUNTRY
AND THEY DON'T WANT TO HAVE
THEIR PRIVACY INFRINGED ON SO
THAT'S ONE ARGUMENT USED AGAINST
ANY SORT OF GUN CONTROL.
I DON'T THINK IT'S A
CONSTITUTIONAL ARGUMENT BUT IT'S
A POLITICAL ARGUMENT THAT A LOT
OF PEOPLE -- IT CARRIES A LOT OF
WEIGHT.
>> HERE'S SOMETHING THAT JUSTICE
SCALIA SAID SHORTLY AFTER THE
AURORA, COLORADO, MASS KILLINGS.
I'M GOING TO PLAY THE CLIP.
>> YES, THERE ARE SOME
LIMITATIONS THAT CAN BE IMPOSED.
WHAT THEY ARE IS WHAT SOCIETY
UNDERSTANDS ARE REASONABLE
LIMITATIONS.
THE AMENDMENT DOES NOT APPLY TO
ARMS THAT CANNOT BE CARRIED.
IT DOESN'T APPLY TO CANONS.
I SUPPOSE THERE ARE HANDHELD
ROCKET LAUNCHES THAT CAN BRING
DOWN AIRPLANES.
IT WILL HAVE TO BE DECIDED.
>> DID YOU GET A CLUE THERE FROM
WHAT KIND OF GUN RESTRICTS
JUSTICE SCALIA MIGHT BE OPEN TO
IN.
>> NOT MANY, IT SOUNDS LIKE.
REMEMBER, HE SAID HAND HELD LIKE
STIN GSTIN GER MISSILES.
MAYBE YES, MAYBE NOT.
HE WAS OBVIOUSLY JUST TALKING
OFF THE CUFF BUT IT'S INDICATIVE
OF HOW UP IN THE AIR THE RULES
ARE HERE.
I THINK MOST OF US ASSUME THAT
THE GOVERNMENT CAN BAN STINGER
MISSILES.
IF YOU'RE STANDING BY AN AIRPORT
WITH A MISSILE THAT CAN SHOOT
DOWN A PLANE, I THINK MOST OF US
ARE RECOGNIZED THAT THAT'S
SOMETHING THAT THE GOVERNMENT
CAN REGULATE.
BUT JUSTICE SCALIA SEEMS UP IN
THE AIR ABOUT IT.
I THINK THAT IS JUST AN
INDICATION OF HOW MUCH THE
HELLER CAN CASE HAS THROWN ALL
OF THESE RULES UP IN THE AIR AND
I WOULDN'T WANT TO BE IN A
POSITION OF GUARANTEEING ONE WAY
OR ANOTHER HOW THE SUPREME COURT
IS GOING TO RULE ON GUN CONTROL
AT THIS POINT.
>> AND NEITHER WOULD I.
JEFFREY, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
JEFF TOOBIN IS OUR SENIOR LEGAL
ANALYST.
>>> SANDY HOOK STUDENTS MAY
DREAD THE DAY THEY MUST RETURN
TO SCHOOL, AT LEAST SOME OF
THEM.
NOW OFFICIALS ARE TRYING TO GIVE
THEM A LITTLE BIT MORE TIME TO
COPE WITH THIS TRAGEDY.
Let's say you want to get ahead
in your career.
How do you get from here...
to here?
At University of Phoenix we're
moving Career Planning forward
so you
can start figuring that out
sooner. ln fact, by thinking
about where
want your education to lead,
while you're still in school,
you might find
the best route...
leads somewhere you weren't
even looking.
Let's get to work.
FIVE DAYS LATER,
I HAD A MASSIVE HEART ATTACK.
BAYER ASPIRIN WAS THE FIRST
THING THE EMTS GAVE ME.
NOW, I'M ON
A BAYER ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Male Announcer ] BE SURE
TO TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE YOU BEGIN
AN ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Woman ]
LEARN FROM MY STORY.
With Olay, here's how.
New Regenerist
Eye and Lash Duo
The cream smooths
the look of lids...
Softens the look of lines.
The serum instantly thickens
the look of lashes.
See Wow!...
Eyes in just one week
With Olay.
>>> SCHOOL OFFICIALS ARE
PLANNING FOR SANDY HOOK STUDENTS
TO GO BACK TO SCHOOL IN JANUARY.
>> THAT'S RIGHT, WOLF.
WE HAVE RECEIVED A LETTER
DETAILING STUDENTS TO RETURN TO
CHALK HILL IN A NEIGHBORING
TOWN.
POLICE WILL BE IN HAND BOTH
INSIDE AND OUT WHEN THEY RESUME
SCHOOL.
STUDENTS AT THE OTHER SCHOOLS
WENT BACK TO CLASS TODAY WITHIN
THE NEWTOWN PUBLIC SCHOOL
SYSTEM.
MARY SNOW HAS BEEN FOLLOWING
THAT.
MARY, WHAT ARE YOU LEARNING?
>> Reporter: KATE, AS YOU KNOW,
AS THIS COMMUNITY MOURNS AND THE
O
OUTPOURING OF SUPPORT CONTINUES,
NEWTOWN SCHOOL DISTRICT REOPENED
ITS DOORS FOR THE FIRST TIME
SINCE THE TRAGEDY ON FRIDAY.
THIS IS A COMMUNITY STILL ON
EDGE AND AT ONE ELEMENT REE
SCHOOL A CALL WAS MADE, THEY
DIDN'T TALK ABOUT THE NATURE OF
THAT CALL BUT IT WAS ENOUGH FOR
SCHOOL OFFICIALS TO TELL
STUDENTS TO STAY HOME AT THAT
ONE SCHOOL.
BUT ELSEWHERE, SCHOOL DID RESUME
TWO HOURS LATER THAN NORMAL.
SCHOOL BUSES ROLLING ONCE AGAIN
AS NEWTOWN STRUGGLES TO RESUME A
SENSE OF NORMALCY BUT IT IS
ANYTHING BUT NORMAL.
FUNERALS WERE HELD NEARBY.
POLICE PRESENCE WERE STEPPED UP.
IN THE MIDST OF IT, SOME PARENT
WELCOMED GETTING BACK TO A
ROUTINE IN THE CLASSROOM.
>> IT'S EXACTLY WHAT THE KIDS
NEED AFTER SUCH A, YOU KNOW,
TERRIBLE TRAGEDY.
A LOT OF THEM DO KNOW WHAT'S
GOING ON.
AND THEY NEED SOMEWHERE, YOU
KNOW, TO GET THEIR THOUGHTS BACK
TO THE FUN STUFF.
>> Reporter: BUT ITS ALSO MEANT
THAT KIDS FROM OTHER SCHOOLS WHO
HAD BEEN SHIELDED FROM WHAT
HAPPENED WOULD NOW RETURN AND
POTENTIALLY HEAR ABOUT THE GRIM
EVENTS THAT HAD TRANSPIRED AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> WHEN I PICKED MY DAUGHTER UP
FROM SCHOOL ON FRIDAY, THE FIRST
WORDS OUT OF HER MOUTH WERE, PA,
WHY ARE YOU PICKING ME UP?
WE'RE HAVING SUCH A GREAT DAY.
AND I NEED TO THANK THE TEACHERS
AND THE STAFF FOR DOING THEIR
BEST TO SHIELD MY CHILD FROM
WHAT HAPPENED.
>> Reporter: BEFORE RETURN ARING
TO CLASS, SCHOOLS ENCOURAGED
PARENTS TO TALK WITH THEIR KIDS
TO TALK ABOUT THE SHOOTINGS
SAYING THAT STAFF CAN'T CONTROL
WHAT CHILDREN HEAR FROM OTHERS.
>> WHEN A CRISIS LIKES THIS
HAPPENS --
>> Reporter: WENDY IS A GRIEF
COUNSELOR IN TOWN WHO HAS BEEN
ADVISING PARENTS ON HOW TO TALK
TO THEIR KIDS.
>> CHILDREN DON'T NEED DETAILS.
ALL THEY NEED TO KNOW IS A FACT.
THAT A BAD THING HAPPENED,
PEOPLE WERE KILLED, AND WE ARE
MAKING OUR SCHOOLS VERY SAFE AND
THIS DOESN'T HAPPEN VERY, VERY
OFTEN AND WE ARE WORKING THAT IT
NEVER WILL HAPPEN AGAIN.
>> Reporter: AND TO PREPARE FOR
STUDENTS RETURNING, THE DISTRICT
MET WITH STAFF FROM BUS DRIVERS
TO TEACHERS ON MONDAY.
AMONG THE THINGS THEY CAUTIONED
THEM ABOUT, THE DANGERS OF
GETTING TOO EMOTIONAL IN FRONT
OF CHILDREN, SOMETHING THAT CAN
BE OVERWHELMING FOR THE KIDS.
>> THAT'S TERRIFYING FOR
CHILDREN BECAUSE WE ARE SUPPOSED
TO BE THE STRENGTH FOR THEM.
WE PROVIDE SECURITY AND SAFETY
AND PREDICTABILITY AND IF THE
TEACHERS FALL APART, THAT'S
GOING TO SCARE THEM.
>>> I'M WOLF BLITZER IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WE'D LIKE TO WELCOME OUR VIEWERS
FROM THE UNITED STATES AND
AROUND THE WORLD.
TODAY STUDENTS TOOK THEIR FIRST
TENTATIVE STEPS TOWARDS SOME
SEMBLANCE OF NORMALITY.
MOST OF THE SCHOOLS REOPENED BUT
NOT THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
WE LEARNED TODAY THAT THE
STUDENTS OF THAT SCHOOL, THE
SITE OF FRIDAY'S LAST SHOOTING,
WON'T RESUME CLASSES UNTIL
JANUARY.
ALSO, THE CONNECTICUT'S MEDICAL
EXAMINER REVEALED THAT NANCY
LANZA WAS SHOT FOUR TIMES IN THE
HEAD WHILE SHE WAS SLEEPING.
HE ALSO SAYS ADAM LANZA DIED OF
A SINGLE GUNSHOT WOUND TO THE
HEAD FIRED FROM A HANDGUN.
SIGNIFICANTLY, THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER ALSO DISCLOSED THAT
HE'S BEEN TOLD LANZA WAS
DIAGNOSED WITH ASPERGER'S
SYNDROME.
OFFICIALS SAY THEY ARE WORKING
TO DETERMINE WHETHER THAT
DIAGNOSIS WAS CORRECT.
OUR NATIONAL CORRESPONDENT,
SUSAN CANDIOTTI, SPOKE WITH AN
ACQUAINTANCE OF THE LA LANZAS A
SHE'S JOINING US NOW.
>> Reporter: WOLF, THIS IS THE
HOME WHERE THE SHOOTER ADAM
LANZA LIVED WITH HIS MOTHER AND
WHETHER POLICE SAY HE SHOT AND
KILLED HIS MOTHER AS SHE WAS
SLEEPING IN HER BEDROOM.
AS YOU INDICATED, HE SHOT HER
FOUR TIMES IN THE HEAD.
AND AMONG THE MANY PEOPLE THAT
ARE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHAT
WENT WRONG, WHAT MADE THIS YOUNG
MAN DO WHAT HE DID ARE PEOPLE
WHO WENT TO SCHOOL WITH HIM.
I SPOKE WITH ONE OF THOSE YOUNG
MEN VERY RECENTLY.
AMONG THE STEADY STREAM OF
PEOPLE DRAWN TO THIS MEMORIAL
HONORING VICTIMS, A FORMER
SCHOOLMATE OF THE ALLEGED
KILLER.
WHEN YOU THINK OF THIS, DOES
YOUR MIND ALSO GO TO YOUR
FRIEND?
>> OBVIOUSLY IT DOES BECAUSE,
YOU KNOW, HE'S A VERY BIG PART
IN THIS EVENT.
I'M NOT REALLY SURE WHAT TO
THINK OF IT.
>> SADLY, HE'S THE REASON FOR
IT.
>> YEAH.
>> ALAN DIAZ, WHEN HE WAS A
SOPHOMORE AT NEWTOWN HIGH SCHOOL
AND DIAZ WAS A FRESHMAN IN 2008.
>> HE WAS A VERY INTELLIGENT
PERSON.
THE WAY HE ACTED AROUND OTHER
PEOPLE WAS JUST VERY WITHDRAWN
AND JUST VERY QUIET.
>> A LITTLE DIFFERENT?
>> YEAH.
>> THEY WERE IN THE HIGH SCHOOL
TECH CLASS TOGETHER, SPENT A LOT
OF TIME ON COMPUTERS.
ADAM HAD HIS OWN STYLE OF
DRESSING.
>> HE HAD LIKE THE STIR OHIO
TYPICAL NERD LOOK, LIKE KHAKI
PANTS, BELT, TUCKED IN SHIRT,
EVEN HAD LIKE A LITTLE COMPUTER
CASE, A BRIEFCASE INSTEAD OF A
BACKPACK LIKE EVERYONE ELSE,
EVEN A POCKET PROTECTOR THAT HE
HAD PENS IN.
>> HE DOESN'T KNOW WHETHER LANZA
WAS BULLIED.
HE KEPT TO HIMSELF.
>> WE ALL KIND OF KNEW THAT HE
HAD PROBLEMS SOCIALLY AND WE
KIND OF HAD A FEELING THAT THERE
MIGHT HAVE BEEN SOMETHING WRONG
WITH HIM BUT OBVIOUSLY WE NEVER
ASKED.
WE NEVER THOUGHT IT WAS OUR
PLACE TO DO SO.
>> BACK THEN, HIS SCHOOLMATE'S
MOM INVITED THEM OVER TO THE
HOUSE TO PLAY VIDEO GAMES.
ONE WAS STARCRAFT, KIND OF A WAR
GAMES IN SPACE.
ANOTHER WAS WAR CRAFT 3 WHERE,
AS THE AD SAYS, SURVIVAL IS A
MATTER OF STRATEGY.
>> WAR CRAFT 3 BASS REALWAS REA.
HE ACTUALLY PICKED UP ON STAR
CRAFT VERY QUICKLY.
>> Reporter: WHEN LANZA QUIT
HIGH SCHOOL AND WAS HOME
SCHOOLED, HE LOST TOUCH.
>> I REMEMBER HER MENTIONING
THAT HE STARTED GOING TO THE
SHOOTING RANGE WITH HER AND MY
INITIAL RESPONSE TO THAT WAS, I
NEVER REALLY IMAGINED ADAM ONE
TO EVEN HOLD A GUN.
>> WHY DO YOU SAY THAT IN.
>> I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE BECAUSE IN MY MIND I DON'T
IMAGINE SHY, QUIET PEOPLE GOING
TO A SHOOTING RANGE.
I NEVER REALLY CAN MAKE THAT
ASSOCIATION.
>> INVESTIGATORS ARE TRACKING
HOW OFTEN LANZA HAD BEEN TO GUN
RANGES.
THEY DON'T YET KNOW HOW MANY SO
FAR.
THEY'VE PROVEN THAT HE WAS AT
TARGET PRACTICE SIX MONTHS AGO
AND FOR SEVERAL YEARS MOTHER AND
SON WENT AT LEAST ONCE TOGETHER.
ALAN'S OLDER SISTER WENT TO
SCHOOL WITH THE SHOOTER'S OLDER
BROTHER AND FRIENDS WITH HIS
MOTHER WHO WENT TO HER BRIDAL
SHOWER LAST YEAR.
>> WHY HER?
SHE WAS JUST -- THANK YOU.
YEAH.
IT WAS A SHOCK.
ALWAYS A HAPPY PERSON.
>> DO YOU NOW THINK OF HIM AS AN
EVIL PERSON BECAUSE OF WHAT HE
DID IN.
>> AT ONE POINT HE WAS A GOOD
KID.
THE EVENTS THAT HE DID THAT DAY
MAY HAVE BEEN EVIL BUT BEFORE
THEN HE WAS JUST ANOTHER KID.
>> UNTIL SOMETHING MADE HIM
SNAP.
NOW PERHAPS, WOLF, PERHAPS WE
MIGHT GET SOME ANSWERS FROM
TOXICOLOGY TESTS.
THIS IS BLOOD WORK THAT THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER'S OFFICE IS
DOING AS PART OF THE AUTOPSY
WHICH MIGHT TELL US WHETHER HE
HAD ANY DRUGS OR CHEMICALS IN
HIS SYSTEM, ADAM LANZA.
HOWEVER, THERE IS ANOTHER
TROUBLING ASPECT OF THIS
INVESTIGATION.
WE ARE HEARING THAT THE
COMPUTERS THAT ARE CURRENTLY
BEING ANALYZED BY THE STATE
POLICE WITH HELP FROM THE FBI,
THAT THERE IS IS DIFFICULTY
DOING THAT, HAVING A HARD TIME
BECAUSE THE COMPUTER WAS SO
BADLY SMASHED AND THE HARD DRIVE
NEARLY DESTROYED THAT
INVESTIGATORS ARE HAVING A VERY
DIFFICULT TIME TRYING TO
RETRIEVE ANY INFORMATION FROM
IT.
INFORMATION, FOR EXAMPLE, ON
WHAT INTERNET SITES HE MIGHT
HAVE VISITED, ANY E-MAILS HE
MIGHT HAVE SET, ANY WEBSITES HE
MIGHT HAVE VISITED.
AND SO THAT, TOO, MIGHT HAVE
GIVEN THEM ANSWERS BUT NOW WE
DON'T KNOW KNOW WHETHER THEY
WILL BE ABLE TO DO THAT.
WOLF?
>> LEARNING A LITTLE BIT MORE
EVERY SINGLE DAY BUT THERE'S
STILL SO MUCH MORE TO LEARN.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI, THANK YOU.
>>> TODAY, CONNECTICUT'S
GOVERNOR SIGNED A PROCLAMATION
TO MAKE THIS FRIDAY A STATE OF
MOURNING.
HE'S ASKING FOR A MOMENT OF
SILENCE AT 9:30 A.M.
THAT'S ABOUT THE SAME TIME THAT
ADAM LANZA SHOWED UP AT THE
SCHOOL AND STARTED SHOOTING.
TODAY I SPOKE WITH THE MAN WHO
HAS BECOME THE PUBLIC FACE OF
THIS INVESTIGATION, THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
LIEUTENANT, PAUL VANCE.
>> LIEUTENANT VANCE, IN YOUR
39-YEAR CAREER, HOW DO YOU
PREPARE FOR THE ENORMITY OF A
TRAGEDY LIKE THIS?
>> TRAINING.
TRAINING.
CONSTANT, CONSTANT TRAINING,
THINGS YOU HOPE YOU WILL NEVER
HAVE TO USE, JUST LIKE THE SIDE
ARM, YOU HOPE YOU NEVER WILL
HAVE TO USE IT.
YOU HAVE TO TRAIN, YOU HAVE TO
PREPARE BECAUSE WHEN YOU GET TO
A SCENE OR A SITUATION, EVEN A
SCENE OF THIS MA NA TUD, YOU
HAVE TO ACT.
THERE'S NO TIME.
>> BECAUSE YOU HAVE EMERGED AS
THE CHIEF SPOKESMAN.
YOU ARE TELLING PEOPLE NOT ONLY
HERE BUT ALL OVER THE WORLD
WHAT'S GOING ON.
IT MUST TAKE A TOLL ON YOU.
>> IT DOES.
BUT OUR TRAINING PREPARES US TO
WORK THROUGH THOSE ISSUES, TO GO
THROUGH SOMETHING LIKE THIS IS
DEVASTATING.
IT'S TRULY DEVASTATING BECAUSE
WE'RE ONLY HUMAN AND WE THINK
ABOUT THE FAMILIES.
WE THINK ABOUT THESE CHILDREN.
WE THINK ABOUT THE PEOPLE THAT
LOST THEIR LIVES.
WE THINK ABOUT THE TEACHERS THAT
PROTECTED THEIR CHILDREN.
AND ALL THOSE THINGS, YOU'RE
PROCESSING BUT YOU HAVE TO SHOVE
IT ASIDE AND MOVE FORWARD AND DO
WHAT YOU'RE TRAINED TO DO.
>> AND YOU MET WITH THESE
FAMILIES OF THESE 26 VICTIMS, 20
KIDS, SIX EDUCATORS.
THAT MUST BE ONE OF THE MOST
DIFFICULT THINGS YOU'VE EVER
DONE IN YOUR LIFE.
>> I WAS PART OF IT BUT, QUITE
FRANKLY, THE PEOPLE THAT WERE
ASSIGNED TO WORK WITH THEM AND
THE ONE ON ONES, IF YOU WILL,
THE INTERVIEWERS THAT HAD TO
INTERVIEW PEOPLE, THOSE ARE
VERY, VERY HARD JOBS, VERY HARD
THINGS TO DO.
THERE ARE SO MANY PEOPLE THAT
HAVE PLAYED SUCH A MAJOR ROLE IN
THIS WHOLE SITUATION THAT IT
SPREAD AMONGST MANY.
>> WAS THERE -- I KNOW THE WHOLE
THING HAS BEEN PAINFUL.
IT'S BEEN PAINFUL FOR ALL OF US.
I CAN ONLY IMAGINE WHAT THE
FAMILIES ARE GOING THROUGH.
BUT WAS THERE ONE MOMENT IN YOUR
MIND THAT STANDS OUT THAT YOU
WILL NEVER FORGET THE REST OF
YOUR LIFE?
>> I THINK THE CRIME SCENE
ITSELF IS SOMETHING THAT HAS
MADE AN INDELIBLE MARK.
IT'S SOMETHING THAT WE WILL
NEVER BE ABLE TO ERASE.
>> YOU MEAN WHEN YOU WALKED INTO
THAT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AND YOU SAW BODIES OF
LITTLE KIDS ON THE FLOOR?
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
YES.
>> HOW CAN YOU EVEN -- THAT MUST
BE SO SHOCKING.
THAT MUST BE SO TRAUMATIC.
>> IT'S AN INLEGALABLE MARK THAT
WILL NEVER GO AWAY.
>> YOU NEVER SAW ANYTHING LIKE
THAT BEFORE IN YOUR LIFE?
>> NO.
>> AND YOU'VE BEEN TO A LOT OF
CRIME SCENES?
>> YES.
>> THIS WAS THE WORST BY FAR?
>> WE WANT TO MAKE SURE THIS
DOESN'T HAPPEN AGAIN.
IT WILL HAPPEN AGAIN.
I KNOW THAT.
YOU KNOW THAT.
WHAT CAN WE DO TO REDUCE THE
CHANCES OF THIS HAPPENING AGAIN?
>> WELL, I THINK EVERYONE'S
LOOKED AT THIS SCENE, THIS
SITUATION, WE'RE ALL PREPARED
EVEN WHEN WE WERE YOUNGER FOR
FIRE DRILLS, WE PREPARE FOR
EMERGENCIES IN THE SCHOOL.
I THINK THAT'S A CONSTANT THING
THAT WE'RE ALWAYS GOING TO DO IN
OUR EDUCATIONAL SYSTEM, REVIEW,
REREVIEW, LOOK AT IT, MAKE SURE
TO CONTINUE TO MAKE OUR MOST
PRECIOUS CHILDREN AS SAFE AS WE
CAN MAKE THEM.
WE HAVE TO.
WE WORKED THROUGH 9/11 AND WE
CONTINUED.
LIFE WENT ON.
I DON'T WANT TO SIMPLIFY
ANYTHING BUT WE'VE GOT TO WORK
THROUGH THIS.
>> DO WE NEED A NATIONAL
COMMISSION TO TAKE A LOOK AT
SCHOOL SAFETY?
>> THAT'S ABOVE ME.
I KNOW ON A LOCAL LEVEL, I'M
SURE OUR TOWN LEADERS, STATE
LEADERS ARE ALL GOING TO
CONTINUOUSLY LOOK AT SCHOOL
SAFETY TO ENSURE THAT OUR
CHILDREN ARE SAFE.
>> LIEUTENANT VANCE, LET ME
THANK YOU FOR WHAT YOU AND THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE HAVE
DONE.
YOU'VE BEEN A REAL SOURCE OF
STRENGTH TO ALL OF US AND AS
JOURNALISTS, AMERICANS, AS
CITIZENS, YOU'VE DONE AN
OUTSTANDING JOB.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I APPRECIATE THAT.
>> THANK YOU.
>> ACROSS NEWTOWN, THIS WAS A
BACK TO SCHOOL DAY UNLIKE ANY OF
THESE PARENTS OR STUDENTS HAVE
FACED BEFORE.
>>> AND LISTENING TO A NEIGHBOR
WHO HAS A TRULY AMAZING STORY TO
TELL.
>> THEY SAID, WE CAN'T GO BACK
TO THAT SCHOOL.
WE CAN'T GO BACK.
>> WE CAN'T GO BACK?
>> OUR TEACHER -- OUR TEACHER'S
DEAD.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
MAKE A WISH!
I WISH WE COULD
LIE HERE FOREVER.
I WISH THIS TEST DRIVE WAS OVER,
SO WE COULD HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
TEST DRIVE!
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A JETTA.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN,
$0 DUE AT SIGNING, $0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
YOU WON'T JUST
FIND US ONLINE,
YOU'LL ALSO FIND US IN PERSON,
WITH DEDICATED SUPPORT TEAMS
AT OVER 500 BRANCHES
NATIONWIDE.
SO WHEN YOU CALL OR VISIT,
YOU CAN ASK FOR A NAME
YOU KNOW.
BECAUSE PERSONAL SERVICE
STARTS WITH A REAL PERSON.
[ Rodger ]
AT SCOTTRADE,
SEVEN DOLLAR TRADES
ARE JUST THE START.
OUR SUPPORT TEAMS
ARE NEARBY,
READY TO HELP.
IT'S NO WONDER SO MANY INVESTORS
ARE SAYING...
[ All ]
I'M WITH SCOTTRADE.
>>> WITH A DEEP BREATH AND
PRAYERS FOR SAFETY, MOST OF
NEWTOWN PARENTS SENT THEIR
CHILDREN BACK TO SCHOOL TODAY.
CNN'S KYUNG WATCHED A NORMAL
ROUTINE THAT HAS UTTERLY
CHANGED.
HOW DID IT GO?
>> IT CHANGED FOREVER, NOT JUST
FOR PEOPLE IN THIS IMMEDIATE
AREA BUT ALL THROUGH THE ENTIRE
CONNECTICUT REGION BECAUSE IF
YOU'RE A PARENT AND YOU HAVE A
CHILD HEADING TO SCHOOL, YOU
CERTAINLY FELT WHAT HAPPENED AT
THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
ESPECIALLY FOR ONE FAMILY, YOU
KNOW, WHO IS TRYING TO RESUME
NORMAL LIFE.
NOTHING NEW AT THE GOVAI HOUSE,
JUST ANOTHER MORNING BRUSHING
TEETH, READYING THE BABY EXCEPT
EVERYTHING HAS CHANGED.
>> HOW CAN'T YOU THINK ABOUT IT?
LIKE IT'S SO CLOSE TO YOU.
>> Reporter: WHAT IS IT LIKE TO
SEND YOUR CHILD OFF INTO THE
WORLD?
>> YOU KNOW, I -- AFTER FRIDAY
I -- I WANTED TO JUST PUT THEM
IN A BUBBLE AND HOME SCHOOL AND
NOT EVER SEND THEM OFF.
>> Reporter: BUT SENDING THEIR
CHILDREN OFF TO SCHOOL IS
EXACTLY WHAT PARENT IN THIS AREA
ARE DOING.
HERE IN NEWTOWN, THE FIRST DAY
BACK IN CLASS HAS MEANT THE
CHILDREN ARE WALKING BY
SATELLITE TRUCKS AND THE
FUNERALS OF FELLOW CHILDREN.
THEY ARE TRYING TO RETURN TO A
FELLOW ROUTINE WHEN NOTHING HERE
IS ORDINARY.
>> THIS IS MY TOWN GOING THROUGH
THIS.
IT'S TOUGH AND I WANT TO BE
THERE FOR THEM.
>> Reporter: MEGAN LIVES A TOWN
AWAY IN NEW MILFORN NOW BUT SHE
GREW UP HERE IN NEWTOWN.
SHE MARRIED HERE, BAPTIZED HERE.
HER FATHER TAUGHT AT SANDY HOOK
WHEN MEGAN WAS A CHILD.
>> I'D NATURALLY LIKE TO KEEP MY
KIDS IN A BUBBLE BUT YOU CAN'T
DO THAT.
THEY NEED TO EXPERIENCE SCHOOL
AND EVERYTHING THAT HELPS THEM
GROW AND MATURE AND IT'S
IMPORTANT.
>> Reporter: SO THEY KEEP GOING.
POLICE OFFICERS ARE AT BOTH
THESE BOYS' SCHOOLS LIKE THEY
ARE ACROSS THE REGION.
THE NEWS CONTINUES TO PLAY OUT
BUT IN THE BACKGROUND, NOT THIS
FAMILY'S FOCUS.
>> HAVE A GOOD DAY.
>> BY, MOM.
>> IN A WAY, IT'S KIND OF
SHOWING THEM THAT, YOU KNOW
WHAT, YOU DIDN'T WIN.
WE'RE GOING TO WIN THIS BY
CONTINUING TO DO THINGS AS
NORMAL AS POSSIBLE.
>> HAVE THE BEST DAY EVER.
I LOVE YOU.
>> SHOWING YOUR KIDS THAT, YOU
KNOW WHAT, IT'S OKAY.
WE'RE GOING TO GO ON WITH LIFE.
>> SEE YOU, BRENT.
>> WE'RE GOING TO KEEP DOING
THINGS THE WAY WE DID IT LAST
WEEK.
WE'RE GOING TO WIN.
>> Reporter: JUST BY LIVING.
I MENTIONED THE POLICE PRESENCE.
IT HAS VARIED AT DIFFERENT
SCHOOLS FROM THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL TO THE HIGH SCHOOL.
I COUNTED THREE PATROL CARS AT
THE HIGH SCHOOL.
PARENTS SAID THAT THEY ARE GLAD
FOR THEIR KIDS TO GO BACK BUT
IT'S CERTAINLY A VERY DIFFICULT
DAY, WOLF.
>> VERY DIFFICULT, INDEED.
I HOPE THAT EVERYONE IS JUST
TRYING TO GET BACK TO NORMAL,
THOUGH IT'S NOT GOING TO BE
EASY.
KYUNG LAH, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WHETHER OR NOT THEY ADMIT IT,
THERE ARE MANY HEROES IN
NEWTOWN, THE TEACHERS AT THE
SCHOOL, THE FIRST RESPONDERS, OF
COURSE, BUT ALSO THE PEOPLE WHO
HAPPENED TO BE IN THE RIGHT
PLACE AT THE RIGHT TIME.
>> THAT'S ABSOLUTELY RIGHT,
WOLF.
GENE ROSEN LIVES DOWN THE
STREET.
FRIDAY MORNING HE DISCOVERED SIX
TERRIFIED CHILDREN ON HIS FRONT
LAWN WHO TOLD HIM THAT THEIR
TEACHER HAD JUST BEEN KILLED.
ROSEN SPOKE WITH CNN'S ERIN
BURNETT.
>> WHEN YOU SAW THOSE CHILDREN
ON YOUR YARD, DID YOU HAVE ANY
IDEA THAT SOMETHING WAS WRONG?
>> I HAD NO IDEA.
I THOUGHT THEY WERE DOING A
SKIT, CUB SCOUTS, GIRL SCOUTS OR
JUST PRACTICING BECAUSE THEY
WERE JUST SITTING SO NICELY BUT
THEN I SAW A MAN IN A VERY
AGITATED WAY SAYING, IT'S GOING
TO BE ALL RIGHT AND HE KEPT
RAISING HIS VOICE ARE AND I
THOUGHT THAT WAS SO STRANGE AND
I CAME TO THE CHILDREN AND THEY
WERE CRYING AND WALING AND
MORTIFIED AND A SCHOOL BUS
DRIVER WAS WITH THEM AND I
INVITED THEM INTO THE HOUSE.
THEY SAID THERE WAS AN INCIDENT
AT THE SCHOOL.
I HAD NO IDEA WHAT IT WAS.
>> AND THE CHILDREN, HOW DID
THEY FIND THE WORDS TO TELL YOU?
THEY TOLD YOU THAT THEIR TEACHER
DIED?
>> THEY TOLD ME.
THEY JUST STARTED TALKING.
THE TWO BOYS MOSTLY TALKED AND
THEY SAID, WE CAN'T GO BACK TO
THAT CAN SCHOOL.
WE CAN'T --
>> WE CAN'T GO BACK?
>> OUR TEACHER -- OUR TEACHER IS
DEAD.
WHAT ARE WE GOING TO DO?
WE DON'T HAVE A TEACHER?
AND I WAS -- I COULD NOT TAKE
THAT IN.
I COULD NOT -- I COULD NOT
ACCEPT THAT.
AND I JUST KEPT LISTENING TO
THEM AND THEN THEY TALKED MORE
AND THE BOY SAID, OH, NO.
IT WAS A BIG GUN AND A SMALL GUN
AND THEN I KNEW -- AND THEN THEY
SAID THERE WAS BLOOD.
THERE WAS BLOOD.
AND THEN THEY SAID HER NAME AND
I PRAYED THAT IT WASN'T THAT
TEACHER AND IT WAS.
IT WAS THAT --
>> VICKY SOTO?
>> IT WAS THAT VERY PRETTY
27-YEAR-OLD TEACHER.
I DON'T KNOW HOW THEY FLED.
I DON'T KNOW IF THEY RAN ALL THE
WAY DOWN THE BOULEVARD, THE
STREET NEXT TO THE FIREHOUSE, I
DON'T KNOW HOW THEY GOT TO MY
HOUSE.
THEY WERE SO BRAVE AND THEY WERE
SO GOOD AND THEY -- I BROUGHT
DOWN SOME TOYS FROM MY
GRANDSON'S TOY CHEST AND I GAVE
THEM SOME JUICE AND WE CALLED
THEIR PARENTS.
THEY WERE VERY BRAVE AND VERY
GOOD AND I WAS AMAZED.
I WAS -- I WAS ASTOUNDED AT WHAT
THEY WERE TELLING ME.
>> I KNOW YOU'RE A PSYCHOLOGIST
BY TRAINING BUT YOU TALK ABOUT
BEING A GRANDFATHER.
JUST THE GRANDFATHER, THAT WAS
YOU AT THAT MOMENT.
>> THAT'S WHAT TRAINED ME.
BEING A GRANDFATHER.
I FELT LIKE I WAS WITH MY
GRANDCHILDREN AND I FELT
PERFECTLY HAPPY WITH THEM.
THAT'S WHAT TRAINED ME.
MY GRANDDAUGHTER AND MY GRANDSON
AND THEY WERE WITH ME AND I FELT
COMFORTABLE.
THEY WERE VERY SWEET AND THEY
CALMED DOWN A LITTLE BUT THEY
WERE SO -- THEY KEPT REPEATING
THAT THEY CAN'T GO BACK TO THE
SCHOOL BECAUSE THEY DON'T HAVE A
TEACHER.
>> AND THEIR GRIEVING IS GOING
TO BE HARD FOR THE ADULTS TO
UNDERSTAND.
IT WILL BE INTENSE.
IT WILL BE DIFFERENT.
WHAT MESSAGE DO YOU HAVE FOR
THOSE CHILDREN THAT CAME ON TO
YOUR YARD?
>> I WANT TO SEE -- I WANT TO BE
REUNITED WITH THEM.
I WANT TO SEE THOSE CHILDREN AND
I WANT TO TELL THEM HOW GOOD AND
BRAVE AND STRONG THEY ARE.
I WANT TO TELL THEIR PARENTS
THAT.
>> IT'S SUCH A SAD STORY.
>> SO SAD.
>> HEARTWREMPBLING STORY ABOUT
THESE AMAZING KIDS WHO WITNESSED
SOMETHING SO HORRIBLE.
WHEN WE COME BACK, THE SEARCH
FOR ANSWERS.
THE CLUES.
MEDICAL INVESTIGATORS ARE
LOOKING FOR.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[ Female Announcer ]
WHAT IF THE NEXT BIG THING,
ISN'T A THING AT ALL?
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
CONNECTING
TO THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME FOR CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
>>> IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
PEOPLE ARE SEARCHING FOR
ANSWERING.
SANJAY GUPTA REPORTS THERE'S ONE
PLACE MEDICAL INVESTIGATORS WILL
START.
THE PAST.
>> FIRST THING YOU NOTICE WHEN
YOU LOOK AROUND NEWTOWN,
EVERYONE HAS THAT QUESTIONING
LOOK.
WHY?
WHAT DID WE MISS, IF ANYTHING?
NO ANSWERS YET, JUST HINDSIGHT.
TO TRY AND MAKE SOME SENSE OF
THE TRAGEDY HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, MEDICAL
INVESTIGATORS WILL OFTEN LOOK
FOR EVIDENCE OF PATTERNS.
I'M NOT TALKING ABOUT LOOKING AT
CLOTHING STYLES OR MUSICAL
PREFERENCES OR LIFESTYLE BUT
RATHER EVIDENCE OF SPECIFIC
PLANS.
THAT COULD GIVE SOME CLUE AS TO
WHAT WAS HAPPENING IN A PERSON'S
MIND OR BRAIN.
IT'S HARD TO KNOW BECAUSE
THANKFULLY THERE ARE RELATIVELY
FEW TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS ONE.
BUT A CLOSE LOOK AT THE TEN MOST
ANALYZED MASSACRES IN HISTORY
PROVIDE SOME INSIGHT.
ACCORDING TO THIS REPORT,
DOCTORS TYPICALLY START BY
PLACING THESE KILLERS INTO THREE
CATEGORIES.
TRAUMATIZED, PSYCHOTIC,
PSYCHOPATH PARTICULAR.
IN 2005, A 16-YEAR-OLD KILLED
NINE PEOPLE AT A SCHOOL IN
MINU
MINNESOTA.
A LOOK INTO HIS PAST REVEALED A
HORRIBLE PAST AND VIRGINIA TECH
SHOOTER KILLED 32 PEOPLE.
SIX WERE MURDERED IN ARIZONA AND
12 LIVES WERE TAKEN IN AN
AURORA, COLORADO, MOVIE THEATER.
IN EACH CASE, THE SHOOTERS
SHOWED PSYCHOTIC BEHAVIOR.
13 PEOPLE WERE KILLED IN
COLUMBINE.
ONE WAS A TEXTBOOK PSYCHOPATH
AND WE KNOW NOW HE EVEN LAUGHED
WHILE GUNNING DOWN HIS VICTIMS.
LOOKING BACK, NONE OF THEM HAD
SNAPPED.
THEY HAD ALL LEFT CLUES PIECED
TOGETHER AFTER IT WAS TOO LATE.
HINDSIGHT.
WE STILL DON'T KNOW MUCH ABOUT
THIS SHOOTER THAT LIVED IN THIS
HOME BUT THERE IS SOMETHING ELSE
TO CONSIDER, WHAT MEDICATIONS,
IF ANY, HE WAS ON.
I'M SPECIFICALLY TALKING ABOUT
ANTIDEPRESSANTS.
IF YOU LOOK AT HOW OTHER
SHOOTINGS LIKE THIS HAVE
HAPPENED, MEDICATIONS WERE A
COMMON FACTOR.
I WANT TO BE CLEAR, NOT THAT
ANTIDEPRESSANTS CAN'T BE
EFFECTIVE BUT THERE'S A
VULNERABLE TIME BETWEEN WHEN
SOMEONE STARTS AND STOPS THESE
MEDICATIONS, COULD LEAD TO
DECREASED JUDGMENT AND MAKING
SOMEONE OUT OF TOUCH.
NONE OF THIS IS AN EXECUTION AND
IT'S NEVER JUST ONE THING.
NONE OF THESE BEHAVIORS WILL
FULLY PREDICT OR EXPLAIN WHY.
BUT SOON AGAIN THERE WILL BE
HINDSIGHT THAT MIGHT JUST HELP
PREVENT ANOTHER TRAGEDY.
IN A SEVEN-YEAR PERIOD THERE
WERE 181 EPISODES OF DRUG SIDE
EFFECTS.
OFTEN IT WAS HIM OR HERSELF
SUICIDE.
IT WAS VERY DIFFICULT FOR THESE
PEOPLE TO GET TREATMENT IN THE
FIRST PLACE.
BACK TO YOU.
>> SANJAY GAUP UPTA REPORTING F
US.
THANK YOU.
>>> SANDY HOOK STUDENTS WON'T GO
BACK TO SCHOOL UNTIL NEXT MONTH.
WE HAVE A GUEST WHO KNOWS WHAT
THEY WILL BE FEELING AS SHE
SURVIVED COLUMBINE HIGH SCHOOL.
THEY ARE NOW REACHING OUT TO
FOLKS HERE IN NEWTOWN.
to offering you
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
low-cost investment options--
like our Exchange
Traded Funds, or ETFs
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
which now have the lowest
operating expenses
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
in their respective
Lipper categories.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Lower than SPDR
and even lower than Vanguard.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
That means with Schwab,
your portfolio has
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
a better chance to grow.
And you can trade
all our ETFs online,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
commission-free, from your
Schwab account.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
So let's talk about
saving money,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
with Schwab ETFs.
Schwab ETFs now have the lowest
operating expenses
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
in their respective
Lipper categories.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
Call 1-800-4SCHWAB
or visit Schwab.com
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
to open an account today.
Funding is easy
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
with Schwab Mobile Deposit.
Investors should consider
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
carefully information
D#: 1-800-345-2550
contained in the prospectus,
cluding investment objectives,
D#: 1-800-345-2550
risks, charges, and expenses.
You can obtain
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
a prospectus by visiting
D#: 1-800-345-2550
w.schwab.com/schwabetfs.
Please read the prospectus
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
carefully before investing.
YOU CAN STAY IN
AND LIKE SOMETHING...
OR YOU CAN GET OUT THERE
AND ACTUALLY LIKE SOMETHING.
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
YEAH WE BOTH RELIEVE COUGHS,
SNEEZING,
ACHES, FEVERS.
AND I RELIEVE
NASAL CONGESTION.
OVERACHIEVER.
[ Female Announcer ] TYLENOL®
COLD MULTI-SYMPTOM NIGHTTIME
RELIEVES NASAL CONGESTION.
NYQUIL® COLD AND FLU DOESN'T.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a
Droid Incredible 4G LTE
by HTC for $49.99.
>>> TODAY MARKED ANOTHER
TERRIBLE MOMENT FOR THE PARENTS
OF TWO STUDENTS KILLED IN THEIR
CLASSROOMS FRIDAY MORNING.
TWO MORE FUNERALS, TWO MORE
BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN LAID TO REST.
>> JAMES MATTIOLI WAS FOUNDLY
KNOWN AS JAY.
HE WAS A FAN OF ARM WRESTLING,
MATH, HAIR GEL, AND HIS BIG
SISTER ANNA.
HE WOULD OFTEN SING AT THE TOP
OF HIS LUNGS AND ASKED HOW OLD
HE WOULD HAVE TO BE TO PERFORM
ON STAGE.
HE ALSO LOVED THE OUTDOORS,
DIVING INTO THE POOL, AND RIDING
HIS BOOK.
PROUD THAT HE DIDN'T NEED
TRAINING WHEELS ANYMORE.
AND JESSICA REKOS WAS KNOWN AS
THE CEO OF HER FAMILY, THE BOSS.
HER PARENTS PROMISED SHE WOULD
GET THE GIFT SHE WANTED MOST, A
HORSE, WHEN SHE TURNED 10.
>> IT'S STILL NOT REAL THAT MY
LITTLE GIRL WHO'S SO FULL OF
LIFE AND WHO WANTS A HORSE SO
BADLY AND WAS GOING TO GET
COWGIRL BOOTS FOR CHRISTMAS
ISN'T COMING HOME.
>> THE SURVIVORS OF THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL FACE
DAUNTING DAUNTING CHALLENGES,
HOPING WHAT THEY HAVE SEEN,
HEARD, AND FELT AND TRYING TO
REBUILT A SENSE OF NORMALITY IN
THEIR LIVES.
BUT THEY AREN'T ALONE.
CRYSTAL MILLER HID FROM THE
KILLER'S AT THE COLUMBINE IN
1999 AND ESCAPED TO SAFETY.
>> I WAS IN THE LIBRARY WHEN
THEY CAME IN AND JUST STARTED
SHOOTING AND SETTING OFF BOMBS.
THEY SAID THAT THEY HAVE WANTED
TO DO THIS THEIR WHOLE LIVES.
>> CRYSTAL MILLER IS NOW PART OF
A SUPPORT GROUP AND SHE'S
JOINING US FROM DEN INJURVER.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
DO YOU REMEMBER WHAT IT WAS LIKE
FOUR DAYS AFTER THE COLUMBINE
MASSACRE, HOW YOU FELT THEN?
>> WOLF, IT'S HARD TO REMEMBER
THE SPECIFIC DAYS.
I FEEL LIKE IN THE IMMEDIATE
DAYS FOLLOWING THE SHOOTING AT
COLUMBINE, THE DAYS BLURRED
TOGETHER.
IT WAS STILL THAT FEELING OF
DISBELIEF AND SHOCK, COMPLETE
AND UTTER SHOCK.
AND AT SOME POINT ALONG THE WAY
IT TURNED INTO EXPERIENCING JUST
A WIDE RANGE OF EE MOWINGS WITH
SUCH INTENSITY, FROM FEAR TO
ANGER TO SADNESS TO GUILT.
JUST TRYING TO WADE THROUGH
THOSE AS A 16-YEAR-OLD GIRL WHO
HAD FACED REALITY OF DEATH
UNDERNEATH THE TABLE AT
COLUMBINE.
IT'S JUST -- IT WAS SO HARD TO
DO AT 16.
I CANNOT EVEN BEGIN TO IMAGINE
WHAT IT LOOKS LIKE FOR THESE
KIDS WHO ARE 6 AND 7, JUST MERE
BABIES.
>> SO HOW DID YOU LEARN TO COPE
WITH THE TRAGEDY THAT YOU
EYEWITNESSED?
>> FOR ME, I REALLY HAD AN
AMAZING SUPPORT SYSTEM.
MY FAMILY, THE COMMUNITY OF
LITTLETON, MY SCHOOL FRIENDS, OF
COURSE THE ADMINISTRATORS,
TEACHERS AT COLUMBINE.
I HAD AN AMAZING CHURCH
COMMUNITY.
PERSONALLY I HAD FAITH THAT I
WAS ABLE TO STAND ON AND NONE OF
IT WAS EASY.
IT WAS THE DARKEST DAYS OF MY
LIFE AS I WAS SCARED TO CLOSE MY
EYES BECAUSE I WOULD RELIVE THE
EVENTS, I WOULD HEAR THE SOUNDS
OF THE GUNS.
I WOULD HEAR THE KILLERS'
VOICES.
I COULD SMELL THE SMELLS OF THE
LIBRARY.
YET IT WAS A JOURNEY.
IT WAS A PROCESS.
I CAN'T REMEMBER ONE DAY WHERE
THINGS SUDDENLY GOT BETTER BUT
IT WAS REALLY A PROGRESSION.
IT WAS TIME THAT IT TOOK TO
HEAL.
IT WAS COMING TOGETHER AND
REALLY SUPPORTING ONE ANOTHER.
JUST AS I SEE THE PEOPLE OF
SANDY HOOK DOING, THE PEOPLE OF
NEWTOWN, CONNE
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT LOOK SO
CLOSE-KNIT AND THAT'S REALLY
CRUCIAL AT THIS TIME.
>> AND ONE THING THAT MANY ARE
SO CONCERNED ABOUT THE CHILDREN
WHOL SURVIVED THIS TRAGEDY HERE
IS HOW THEY ARE GOING TO COPE
WHEN THEY REALIZE AND PROBABLY
HAVE AT THIS POINT THAT THEY
HAVE LOST THEIR FRIENDS, 13
PEOPLE WERE KILLED AT COLUMBINE.
DID YOU LOSE ANY FRIENDS?
>> I DID.
I KNEW SEVERAL OF THE STUDENTS,
THE TEACHER, MR. SANDERS, HE WAS
MY COACH FOR SOFTBALL,
BASKETBALL, TRACK.
WHAT'S SO HARD IS GOING BACK AND
YOU HAVE AN EMPTY CHAIR NEXT TO
YOU OR WE GO TO GRADUATION AND
YOU KNOW THAT YOU HAVE
CLASSMATES THAT ARE SUPPOSED TO
BE GRADUATING WITH YOU.
IT'S -- IT LEAVES A VOID THAT
CANNOT BE FILLED AND FOR THESE
YOUNG KIDS, I THINK WHAT BREAKS
MY HEART THE MOST IS THESE YOUNG
KIDS CAN'T UNDERSTAND THAT THAT
HAPPENED AT THEIR SCHOOL AND THE
BAD GUY IS GONE.
THEY ARE GOING HOME AND THEY
THINK THAT THE BAD GUY IS IN
THEIR ROOM OR IN THEIR HOUSE AND
IT'S HARD FOR THEM TO
CONTEXTUA
CONTEXTUALIZE THAT AND EVEN
AFTER THE CAMERAS ARE GONE AND
THE PEOPLE DISAPPEAR THAT THEY
ARE STILL NOT ALONE.
THAT THERE'S A NATION STILL
GRIEVING.
THAT UNFORTUNATELY THERE'S OTHER
SURVIVORS OUT THERE WHO CAN
RELATE, WHO LOVE THEM AND ARE
NOT GOING ANYWHERE AND I THINK
THAT'S WHAT WE NEED TO REMEMBER.
WE HAVE TO BE THERE IN THE LONG
TERM WHEN THESE KIDS DO BEGIN TO
REALIZE THE REALITY OF WHAT IS
HAPPENING AND THAT WE CANNOT
FORGET THIS COMMUNITY.
WE HAVE TO CONTINUE TO STAND
BEHIND THEM, SUPPORT THEM, DO
WHATEVER WE CAN TO LEND A HAND
BECAUSE THAT'S WHEN THINGS GET
REAL IS WHEN YOU FEEL ISOLATED
AND ALONE AND REALITY SINKS IN.
>> WE HEAR YOU'RE COMING TO COME
TO NEWTOWN.
HOW DO YOU WANT TO HELP?
>> I DO.
I WANT TO COME NOT BECAUSE I
FEEL LIKE I HAVE ANYTHING THAT I
CAN SAY THAT -- THERE'S NO
FIVE-STEP PLAN TO WALK THROUGH
TRAGEDY AND THROUGH TRAUMA.
I WANT TO WRAP MY ARMS AROUND
PEOPLE, CRY WITH THEM, HEAR
THEIR STORIES, JUST GRIEVE WITH
THIS COMMUNITY.
BUT WE HOPE TO COME AGAIN WHEN
ALL OF THE CAMERAS ARE GONE AND
THE WORLD KIND OF GOES BACK TO
THE DAY TO DAY, WE WANT TO COME,
WE WANT TO BRING TEDDY BEARS AND
JUST LOVE ON THE COMMUNITY
THERE.
JUST AS WE WERE LOVED ON AT
COLUMBINE AND IN THE LITTLETON
COMMUNITY.
>> AND EVERYBODY WANTS TO KNOW
WHY, WHY SOMETHING LIKE THIS
COULD HAPPEN, WHY SOMETHING LIKE
COLUMBINE CAN HAPPEN.
IF WE FIND OUT THAT THE
SURVIVORS HERE, THE FAMILIES
FIND OUT WHY, WILL THAT MAKE A
DIFFERENCE?
WILL THAT HELP?
DID IT HELP YOU?
>> YOU KNOW, I'M NOT SURE THAT
WE STILL KNOW WHY THE TWO
KILLERS THAT COLUMBINE DID WHAT
THEY DID.
I'M NOT SURE WE EVER HAVE
ANSWERS TO SOME OF THESE
QUESTIONS.
BECAUSE I THINK IF WE REALLY
KNEW THAT WE WOULD SEE THESE
THINGS COME TO AN END AND,
UNFORTUNATELY, EVEN AS YOU SAID
BEFORE, WOLF, THEY CONTINUE TO
HAPPEN.
I'M NOT SURE IF -- I MEAN,
ANSWERING A KBE ISN'T GOING TO
BRING BACK THESE 26 AMAZING
LIVES THAT WE'VE LOST.
SOME IT MAY BRING SOME
CONSOLATION, IT MAY BRING SOME
UNDERSTANDING.
BUT THE FACT IS THAT THERE'S 20
BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN WHO WERE
TAKEN ALL TOO SOON AND SICK
ADULTS WHO AS WELL WERE TAKEN
ALL TOO SOON FROM THIS EARTH.
>> CRYSTAL, THANKS SO MUCH FOR
SHARING YOUR STORY.
I'M SURE YOU WILL BE A SOURCE OF
COMFORT FOR A LOT OF THE FOLKS
HERE AT NEWTOWN.
WE APPRECIATE YOU JOINING US.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR HAVING
ME.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> THERE'S A GROWING DEBATE
OVER VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES AT THE
SAME TIME.
WHAT YOU NEED TO KNOW, WHAT YOU
CAN DO TO PROTECT YOUR KIDS.
THAT'S NEXT.
BEGIN.
TOMATO,
OBVIOUSLY.
HAHA. THERE'S MORE
THAN THAT THOUGH,
THERE'S A KICK TO IT.
WAHLALALALALLALA!
SMOOTH, BUT CRISP.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE DRINKING
A FOOD THAT'S A DRINK,
OR A DRINK THAT'S A FOOD,
WOOOOOH!
[ Male Announcer ] TASTE IT
AND DESCRIBE THE INDESCRIBABLE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
>>> POLICE SAY ADAM LANZA
BROUGHT FOUR WEAPONS, FOUR
WEAPONS TO THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HERE IN
NEWTOWN AND NOW CALLS FOR
CHANGES TO GUN CONTROL LAWS ARE
GROWING LOUDER AND LOUDER.
AFTER DAYS OF SILENCE, ONE VOICE
FINALLY JOINING THE CONVERSATION
IS THE NATIONAL RIFLE
ASSOCIATION, BETTER KNOWN AS
NRA.
EMILY SCHMIDT IS JOINING US WITH
MORE OF THIS STORY.
WHAT IS GOING ON?
>> WOLF, THE NRA HAS SAID ALMOST
NOTHING SINCE LAST WEEK'S
SHOOTING.
LATE THIS AFTERNOON, THAT ALL
CHANGED WITH THIS STATEMENT
SAYING, OUT OF RESPECT FOR THE
FAMILIES AND AS A MATTER OF
COMMON DECENCY, WE HAVE GIVEN
TIME FOR MOURNING, PRAYER, AND
INVESTIGATION OF FACTS BEFORE
COMMENTING.
NOW THE NRA IS SET TO HOLD A
NEWS CONFERENCE ON FRIDAY, ONE
FULL WEEK AFTER THE SHOOTING.
IT COULD BE A TEST OF THE NRA'S
CLOUT IN A POLITICAL LANDSCAPE
POTENTIALLY ALTERED.
>> FROM ALL OF US HERE AT
NRA.COM, OUR HEARTS GO OUT TO
THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AND THE FOLKS WHO
ARE GRIEVING TONIGHT AFTER THE
HORRENDOUS MURDERS AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
>> THE STATEMENT IS A DEPARTURE
FROM HOW THE NRA HAS HANDLED
PREVIOUS GUN-RELATED TRANL DEES.
UNTIL THE FACTS ARE THOROUGHLY
KNOWN, NRA WILL NOT HAVE ANY
COMMENT.
THAT WAS ALMOST IDENTICAL TO THE
COMMENTS FOLLOWING OTHER
HIGH-PROFILE SHOOTINGS.
THE NRA IS PREPARED TO OFFER
MEANINGFUL CONTRIBUTIONS TO MAKE
SURE THIS NEVER HAPPENS AGAIN
BUT HAS NOT GONE INTO DETAIL
WHAT THOSE CONTRIBUTIONS MAY
PROVE TO BE.
>> I'M SURE THERE'S GOING TO BE
A QUICK, QUICK LIVELY DEBATE
COMING UP.
WE'LL SEE WHAT HAPPENS AT THE
NEWS CONFERENCE THAT THE NRA IS
HOLDING THIS FRIDAY IN
WASHINGTON.
EMILY, THANKS VERY MUCH.
>>> QUESTIONS ARE BEING RAISED
OVER THE ROLE THAT VIOLENT VIDEO
GAMES MIGHT HAVE PLAYED IN THIS
TRAGEDY AS WELL.
PEOPLE WHO KNEW THE GUNMAN SAY
HE ENJOYED PLAYING THOSE VIOLENT
VIDEO GAMES, LIKE ONE CALLED
STARCRAFT.
IS THERE ANY LINK BETWEEN THE
GAMES AND REAL-LIFE VIOLENCE?
OUR SENIOR MEDICAL CORRESPONDENT
ELIZABETH COHEN IS JOINING US
WITH MORE ON THIS.
THIS DEBATE OVER VIOLENT VIDEO
GAMES HAS ALSO INTENSIFIED.
>> IT IS INTENSIFYING AND IF YOU
LOOK AT THE LITERATURE, THERE'S
A REAL CONFLICT OVER WHETHER OR
NOT THESE GAMES CAN ACTUALLY
MAKE SOMEONE VIOLENT SOME OF THE
STUDIES SAY, NO, THEY ARE NOT.
THEY GET THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN
REALITY AND FANTASY.
THEY GET THAT THESE ARE JUST
GAMES BUT OTHER STUDIES SHOW
THAT THERE IS AN ASSOCIATION.
ONE STUDY WAS REALLY
INTERESTING, ONE GROUP PLAYED
VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES AND THE
OTHER GROUP PLAYED NONVIOLENT
VIDEO GAMES AND THEY STAGED A
FIGHT AND THE FOLKS WHO HAD BEEN
WATCHING THE VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES
WERE LESS LIKELY TO HELP OUT.
THEY WERE SLOWER TO TRY TO HELP
THE PEOPLE WHO WERE FIGHTING AND
STOP THE FIGHT AND THEIR
CONCLUSION WAS THAT PERHAPS IN
SOME WAY THEY HAD BEEN
DESENSITIZED BECAUSE THEY FELT
THAT THE FIGHTING REALLY WASN'T
THAT BAD.
AFTER WATCHING THE GAMES, THE
REAL-LIFE FIGHT DIDN'T SEEM THAT
BAD.
WOLF?
>> YOU KNOW, ELIZABETH, A LOT OF
PARENTS ARE WATCHING THEIR --
MAYBE THEIR KIDS PLAY A LOT OF
THESE GAMES ALL THE TIME.
SO WHAT CAN THEY DO IF THEY
BEGIN TO GET WORRIED ABOUT THEIR
KIDS SPENDING AN AWFUL LOT OF
TIME WITH THESE VIOLENT GAMES?
>> YOU KNOW, I THINK IF PARENTS
ARE WORRIED, THEY -- I'M GOING
TO GO OUT ON A LIMB HERE AS AN
EMPOWERED PARENT AND SAY, NO.
I DON'T LIKE THESE GAMES.
THERE'S A MILLION THINGS YOU CAN
DO.
STOP PLAYING THEM F YOU FEEL
LIKE YOUR KIDS ARE PLAYING THEM
AND IT'S OKAY AND I WOULD URGE
TO YOU DO THESE THREE THINGS.
KNOW THE RATING OF THE GAME THAT
THEY ARE PLAYING AND WATCH IT
ONLINE.
IF YOUR CHILD IS PLAYING THIS
GAME, WATCH IT YOURSELF.
THEY MAY BE PLAYING IT FOR HOURS
ON END.
ALSO, HAVE THEM PLAY THE GAME IN
A COMMON FAMILY SPACE.
THEY SHOULDN'T BE IN THEIR
BEDROOM DOING IT.
YOU DON'T KNOW HOW LONG THEY ARE
GOING TO GO ON AND PLAY THIS
GAME AND WHAT ELSE THEY ARE
PLAYING.
DO IT WHERE ELSE YOU CAN WATCH
THEM.
ALSO, MONITOR YOUR CHILD.
IF YOUR CHILD IS HAVING FIGHTS
AT SCHOOL, IF YOUR CHILD IS NOT
DOING WELL AT SCHOOL, IF THE
TEACHER IS TELLING YOU THAT YOUR
CHILD IS HAVING BEHAVIORAL
ISSUES, THEN YOU SHOULD PAY
ATTENTION TO THAT AND REMEMBER
THERE MIGHT BE A LINK TO THESE
GAMES.
WOLF, A PSYCHOLOGIST GAVE US A
REALLY GREAT PIECE OF ADVICE.
THEY SAID, PARENT DON'T ALWAYS
NOTICE THESE BEHAVIORAL CHANGES
BUT SAY GRANDMA COMES TO VISIT
AND SAYS SOMETHING IS OFF HERE.
LISTEN TO THE PEOPLE YOU SEE ON
OCCASIONS, THEY MAY NOTICE THE
CHANGES BETTER THAN YOU.
>> THAT'S A GOOD POINT.
THANKS VERY MUCH, ELIZABETH, FOR
THAT.
>>> AT THE TOP OF THE HOUR,
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE THE VERY
LATEST ON THE INVESTIGATION HERE
IN CONNECTICUT.
WHAT EXACTLY IS GOING ON?
LATER, A BOYFRIEND REMEMBERS A
TEACHER-TURNED HERO WHO LOST HER
LIFE TRYING TO STAY HER
STUDENTS.
I ALWAYS WAIT
UNTIL THE LAST MINUTE.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME FOR CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
We are gathered here today to
celebrate the union of
Tim and Laura.
It's amazing how appreciative
ople are when you tell them
they could save a lot of money
on their car insurance
by switching to GEICO...they may
even make you their best man.
May I have the rings please?
Ah, Helzberg Diamonds.
Nice choice, Mate.
...and now in the presence
of these guests
we join this loving couple.
Oh dear...
GEICO. 15 minutes could save you
15% or more on car insurance.
IT'S LOTS OF THINGS.
ALL WAKING UP.
CONNECTING
TO THE GLOBAL PHENOMENON
WE CALL
THE INTERNET OF EVERYTHING.
♪
IT'S GOING TO BE AMAZING.
AND EXCITING.
AND MAYBE, MOST REMARKABLY,
NOT THAT FAR AWAY.
WE'RE GOING TO
WAKE THE WORLD UP.
AND WATCH, WITH EYES WIDE,
AS IT GETS TO WORK.
CISCO.
TOMORROW STARTS HERE.
>>> WHILE MUCH OF PRESIDENT
OBAMA'S ATTENTION CERTAINLY HAS
BEEN FOCUSED ON HIS
ADMINISTRATION'S RESPONSE TO GUN
VIOLENCE, WHAT HAS HAPPENED HERE
IN CONNECTICUT AND
UNDERSTANDABLY SO, HE'S ALSO
BEEN TALKING WITH THE HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER ABOUT A
DEAL TO TRY TO AVOID HUGE TAX
INCREASES, THE MASSIVE SPENDING
CUTS SCHEDULED TO HIT IN JUST 14
DAYS.
CNN'S SENIOR CONGRESSIONAL
CORRESPONDENT, DANA BASH IS
OUTSIDE A MEETING OF HOUSE
REPUBLICANS.
THERE'S BEEN UPS AND DOWNS.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
WHAT ARE THEY DISCUSSING, DANA?
WHAT'S THE VERY LATEST.
>> HOUSE REPUBLICANS ARE MEETING
RIGHT DOWN THE HALL FROM WHERE I
AM RIGHT NOW.
THEY'RE TALKING ABOUT WHETHER OR
NOT THEY HAVE THE VOTES FOR A
DOOMSDAY KIND OF PROPOSAL THAT
THE SPEAKER FIRST PROPOSED THIS
MORNING.
THIS HAS BEEN SOMETHING THAT
REPUBLICANS HAVE BEEN MULLING
FOR WEEKS.
BUT BECAUSE RIGHT NOW WE ARE ONE
WEEK AWAY FROM CHRISTMAS AND IT
WAS NOW OR NEVER.
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER
NEGOTIATING BY PHONE WITH THE
PRESIDENT MONDAY AFTERNOON.
THE SPEAKER'S OFFICE RELEASED
THIS PHOTO TO SHOW HE IS TRYING
TO CUT A BROAD DEAL TO REDUCE
THE DEFICIT AND AVERT THE FISCAL
CLIFF, EVEN THOUGH HE'S ALSO NOW
PURSUING WHAT HE CALLS PLAN "B."
>> OUR PLAN "B" WOULD PROTECT
AMERICAN TAXPAYER, WHO MAKE A
MILLION DOLLARS OR LESS AND HAVE
ALL OF THEIR CURRENT RATES
EXTENDED.
>> ACCORDING TO SOURCES IN THE
ROOM, THE SPEAKER DESCRIBED THIS
BACKUP PLAN TO HOUSE REPUBLICANS
AS A WAY TO TRY TO INOCULATE THE
GOP FROM POLITICAL BLAME IF
FISCAL CLIFF COMPROMISE TALKS
FAIL.
>> THE POINT WAS, WE HAVE TO
FACE REALITY.
THE REALITY IS THAT THE
PRESIDENT WAS RE-ELECTED, THAT
TAXES, IF WE DO NOTHING ON EVERY
AMERICAN ARE GOING UP ON JANUARY
THE 1st.
>> Reporter: ANOTHER GOAL OF
THIS NEW PLAN "B" TACTIC, TRY TO
FORCE THE PRESIDENT TO AGREE
THAT ANY PACKAGE TO REDUCE THE
DEFICIT BE EQUAL PARTS TAX
INCREASES AND SPENDING CUTS.
>> THAT, AT THIS POINT, WOULD BE
MY VERSION OF A BALANCED
APPROACH.
>> Reporter: PART OF THE
REPUBLICAN STRATEGY IS ALSO TO
CALL THE DEMOCRATS' BLUFF.
JUST TWO YEARS AGO, HIGH-PROFILE
DEMOCRATS CAME UP WITH THE IDEA
OF EXTENDING TAX CUTS FOR
INCOMES UP TO $1 MILLION.
NOW DEMOCRATS THINK THEY HOLD
THE CARDS AND SAY, NO WAY.
>> EVERYONE SHOULD UNDERSTAND,
BOEHNER'S PROPOSAL WILL NOT PASS
THE SENATE.
>> Reporter: THE WHITE HOUSE
ARGUES THE PRESIDENT GAVE A LOT
OF GROUND IN A PROPOSAL LEAKED
TO REPORTERS MONDAY NIGHT,
MAKING CONCESSIONS TO THE GOP
POSITION ON TAX RATE INCREASES
AND SPENDING CUTS.
IN FACT, A DEMOCRATIC SOURCE IN
THE ROOM TELLS CNN THE
PRESIDENT'S CONGRESSIONAL
LIAISON GOT AN EARFUL AT A
MEETING OF HOUSE DEMOCRATS FOR
AGREEING TO CHANGE THAT WOULD
EFFECTIVELY MAKE SOCIAL SECURITY
CHECKS SMALLER.
>> THE PRESIDENT HAS ALWAYS
SAID, AS PART OF THIS PROCESS,
WHEN WE'RE TALKING ABOUT THE
SPENDING CUT SIDE OF THIS, THAT
IT WOULD REQUIRE TOUGH CHOICES
BY BOTH SIDES.
AND THAT IS CERTAINLY THE CASE,
IF YOU WANT TO REACH AN
AGREEMENT.
>> Reporter: NOW, AS FAR AS THIS
REPUBLICAN PLAN "B" PROPOSAL,
WHICH AGAIN, THEY'RE DISCUSSING
THE DOWN THE HALL, AS WE SPEAK,
A REPUBLICAN SENATOR I TALKED TO
SAID HE BELIEVES THAT THIS IS
IMPORTANT TO DO TO SORT OF GET
THE TAX RATE ISSUE, THE VERY
DIVISIVE TAX RATE ISSUE, OFF THE
TABLE, IN THE HOPES THAT WHEN
THE VOTES ARE TAKEN AND YOU SEE
THAT PROBABLY NONE OF THIS CAN
ACTUALLY PASS, IT WILL CLEAR THE
WAY, FINALLY, FOR THE PRESIDENT
AND THE SPEAKER TO GET THAT
BROAD $2 TRILLION DEAL TO REDUCE
THE DEFICIT AND AVERT THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
WOLF?
>> THEY STILL HAVE PLENTY OF
WORK TO DO, THE PRESIDENT AND
THE SPEAKER.
NOT ONLY BRIDGING THEIR GAPS,
BUT MAKING SURE THEY'VE GOT
THEIR OWN PEOPLE ON BOARD TO
SUPPORT WHATEVER COMPROMISES
THEY ACHIEVE.
DANA, THANK YOU.
CNN'S ANDERSON COOPER HAS SPOKEN
WITH THE PARENTS OF ONE OF THE
VICTIMS.
THEY TOLD THEM HOW THEY INTEND
TO LIVE THEIR LIVES TO HONOR
THEIR LITTLE GIRL'S MEMORY.
ANDERSON WILL JOIN US WITH THEIR
STORY.
THAT'S COMING UP IN OUR NEXT
HOUR.
I ALWAYS WAIT
UNTIL THE LAST MINUTE.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME FOR CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
WHAT STARTS
WITH ADDING A FRIEND...
♪
...COULD END
WITH ADDING A CLOSE FRIEND.
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
>>> WE'RE HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
IT'S A SMALL NEW ENGLAND TOWN.
MANY PEOPLE SAY THEY MOVED HERE
BECAUSE OF THE FABULOUS SCHOOLS
AND BECAUSE IT'S A SAFE, SBRIMT
COMMUNITY.
IN THE FACE OF THE HORRIBLE
REASON WE'RE HERE, THOUGH, THE
TOWN IS SHOWING REMARKABLE,
REMARKABLE STRENGTH RIGHT NOW.
ALL OF US ARE SO IMPRESSED.
DON LEMON IS HERE IN NEWTOWN AS
WELL.
HE'S AT ONE OF THESE MANY
MEMORIALS THAT HAVE SPRUNG UP
THROUGHOUT THE TOWN.
IT'S POURING RAIN OUTSIDE, NOW,
DON, BUT TELL OUR VIEWERS WHAT'S
GOING ON.
>> Reporter: WELL, THE PEOPLE
ARE DROPPING OFF THINGS AND
THERE'S HARDLY ANY ROOM HERE.
AND BEFORE I SHOW YOU AROUND A
LITTLE BIT, WOLF, I WANT TO TALK
TO YOU ABOUT TWO OF THE YOUNGEST
VICTIMS, TWO OF THE VICTIMS WHO
WERE LAID TO REST TODAY.
LITTLE JAMES MATTIOLI AND ALSO
LITTLE JESSICA REKOS, BOTH OF
THEM 6 YEARS OLD.
I WANT TO TELL YOU ABOUT JAMES
FIRST.
FONDLY KNOWN AS JAY IN HIS
FAMILY, AND HE WAS SUCH A
FIREBALL.
HE LIKED WRESTLING AND MATH, HE
LOVED TO FIX HIS HAIR, HE LIKED
HAIR GEL, BUT MORE IN LOVE WITH
HIS BIGGER SISTER, WHOSE NAME
WAS ANA.
THEY SAY WHAT THEY'RE GOING TO
REMEMBER ABOUT HIM MOST THAT HE
OFTEN SUNG AT THE TOP OF HIS
LUNGS AND HE COULDN'T WAIT UNTIL
HE WAS OLD ENOUGH TO SING ON
STAGE.
HE SAID HE LOVED THE OUTDOORS,
DIVING INTO POOLS, RIDING ON HIS
BIKE, AND HE WAS SO HAPPY THAT
RECENTLY HE DIDN'T NEED HIS
TRAINING WHEELS TO RIDE HIS
BICYCLE.
AND THEN THERE IS 6-YEAR-OLD
JESSICA REKOS, WHO'S KNOWN AS
THE CEO OF HER FAMILY AND THEY
CALLED HER THE BOSS BECAUSE SHE
LIKED TO PLAN EVERYTHING.
AND HER MOM ALSO SPOKE ABOUT
HER.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> IT'S STILL NOT REAL THAT MY
LITTLE GIRL, WHO'S SO FULL OF
LIFE, AND WHO WANTS A HORSE SO
BADLY, AND WHO'S GOING TO GET
COWGIRL BOOTS FOR CHRISTMAS,
ISN'T COMING HOME.
>> Reporter: MY GOD, THE
STRENGTH OF THAT MOTHER.
SHE WANTED A HORSE BY THE TIME
SHE WAS 10.
SADLY, WOLF, SHE DIDN'T MAKE IT.
BUT THEY SAID SHE WAS GOING TO
GET COWGIRL BOOTS THIS
CHRISTMAS, AND THAT'S WHAT SHE
WANTED MORE THAN ANYTHING,
BESIDES THAT HORSE.
BUT SADLY, THAT'S NOT GOING TO
HAPPEN.
SO MANY STORIES, SO MANY STORIES
LIKE THAT.
TWO OF THE PEOPLE WHO ARE YOUNG
VICTIMS, WHO WERE LAID TO REST
TODAY.
WOLF?
>> DON LEMON WATCHING THIS
STORY, DOING A VERY, VERY
EXCELLENT JOB FOR US.
DON, THANK YOU.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
A LOT OF TOUGH CONVERSATIONS
HERE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
TODAY.
MANY OF THESE CONVERSATIONS SO,
SO PAINFUL, AS SO MANY STUDENTS
WHO WENT BACK TO SCHOOL FACED
THEIR FEARS AFTER THE SHOOTING
MASSACRE.
WE'RE LEARN GRUESOME NEW DETAILS
ABOUT THE WAY THE SHOOTER, ADAM
LANZA, AND HIS MOTHER, NANCY,
DIED.
SHE WAS IN HER PAJAMAS WHEN HE
KILLED HER.
AND IN THE WAKE OF THIS TRAGEDY,
A FIERCE NEW PUSH FOR GUN
CONTROL FROM A CLUB NO ONE
WANTED TO JOIN.
>> I'M THE FATHER OF DANIEL
MAUZNER WHO WAS KILLED IN THE
MASSACRE AT COLUMBINE HIGH
SCHOOL.
>> OUR DAUGHTER, JESSICA
REDFIELD GHAWI WAS KILLED IN
AURORA ON JULY 20th OF THIS
YEAR.
>>> I'M WOLF BLITZER, REPORTING
FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE WANT TO WELCOME OUR VIEWERS
IN THE UNITED STATES AND AROUND
THE WORLD.
RIGHT NOW, POLICE ARE WORKING
AROUND THE CLOCK TO SOLVE THE
MYSTERY OF WHY THE 20-YEAR-OLD
ADAM LANZA GUNNED DOWN 20
STUDENTS AND SIX EDUCATORS IN
THIS SMALL TOWN.
WE'RE LEARNING ABOUT DETAILS
FROM THE INVESTIGATION.
OUR NATIONAL CORRESPONDENT,
DEBORAH FEYERICK, HAS MORE.
>> Reporter: WOLF, INVESTIGATORS
ARE GETTING CLOSER.
HOWEVER, THEY HAVE YET TO
UNDERSTAND THE EXACT MOTIVE.
POLICE INVESTIGATORS RETURN TO
THE HOME OF THE GUNMAN TUESDAY.
INVESTIGATORS ARE HAVING A HARD
TIME RETRIEVING DATA FROM A
BADLY DAMAGED COMPUTER FOUND
INSIDE THE HOUSE, ACCORDING TO A
LAW ENFORCEMENT SOURCE, BECAUSE
THE HARD DRIVE WAS SHATTERED.
NOT ONLY DOES IT APPEAR ADAM
LANZA TRIED TO ERASE HIS DIGITAL
FOOTSTEPS, HE SHOT THE ONLY
WITNESS WHO COULD HAVE MOST
FULLY EXPLAINED WHAT WAS GOING
ON INSIDE HIM.
HIS MOTHER, NANCY, SHOT FOUR
TIMES IN THE HEAD, AS SHE SLEPT
IN HER BED, LIKELY EARLY FRIDAY,
THE AUTOPSY SHOWS.
UNDER THE TERMS OF HER 2009
DIVORCE AGREEMENT, SHE WAS THE
ONE RESPONSIBLE FOR PAYING HER
SON'S PSYCHIATRIC OR
PSYCHOLOGICAL EXPENSES, PLUS
COSTS OF ANY PRESCRIPTION
MEDICATION NOT COVERED BY
INSURANCE.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER'S WAITING
FOR THE RESULTS OF THE
TOXICOLOGY TESTS PERFORMED ON
ADAM LANZA TO SEE IF HE WAS ON
ANY MEDICATIONS OR DRUGS THAT
MAY HAVE POTENTIALLY TRIGGERED
THE DEADLY RAMPAGE.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER ALSO
WORKING WITH INVESTIGATORS TO
DETERMINE IF LANZA WAS CORRECTLY
DIAGNOSED WITH ASPERGER'S OR
WHETHER ANYONE ELSE WAS AT PLAY.
A FAMILY FRIEND, WHO HAD WORKED
ON THE LANZA HOME, TELLS CNN,
NANCY LANZA HAD PUSHED HARD TO
MAINSTREAM HER SON, MIXING HIM
IN WITH OTHER STUDENTS,
APPARENTLY UNSUCCESSFULLY.
THE FRIEND SAYS WHILE HE WAS IN
THE HOME EARLIER THIS YEAR, HE
DID SEE ADAM LANZA, BUT LANZA
REFUSED TO ENGAGE IN ANY SORT OF
CONVERSATION OR EVEN MAKE EYE
CONTACT.
IT APPEARS AS THERE'S NO RECORD
OF ADAM LANZA FROM 2009 ON.
THAT WAS THE LAST TIME HE WAS
REGISTERED IN ANY SORT OF CLASS.
THE LAST SIGHTING, A COUPLE OF
MONTHS AGO, BACK AT A SHOOTING
RANGE WHERE HIS MOM TOOK HIM,
BECAUSE HE DIDN'T WANT TO LEAVE
HIM ALONE.
WOLF?
>> DEBORAH FEYERICK, THANKS VERY
MUCH.
A VERY SMALL STEP BACK TO NORMAL
TODAY.
MOST OF THE NEWTOWN STUDENTS,
THEY RETURNED TO SCHOOL FOR THE
FIRST TIME SINCE THE MASSACRE
WITH POLICE STANDING GUARD.
KATE BALDUAN IS HERE WATCHING
WHAT'S GOING ON.
YOU HAVE SOME NEW INFORMATION
ABOUT THIS RETURN TO SCHOOL?
>> RETURN TO SCHOOL FOR THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
STUDENTS.
IN A LETTER TO BOTH FAMILY AND
STAFF, THE SCHOOL SUPERINTENDENT
SAID THAT THEY WILL NOT BE
RETURNING TO CLASS UNTIL AFTER
THE HOLIDAY, IN JANUARY.
THERE HAD BEEN SOME QUESTIONS
THIS WEEK ON WHEN THEY WOULD.
IN THAT LETTER, THE SCHOOL
SUPERINTENDENT, JANET ROBINSON
WROTE THIS IN PART, WOLF.
SHE WROTE, "WE NEED TO TEND TO
OUR TEACHERS' AND STUDENTS'
NEEDS TO FEEL COMFORTABLE AFTER
THIS TRAUMA IN THIS NEW PLACE."
IN THE MEANTIME, SOME 50, 75
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN WORKING AROUND
THE CLOCK IN THIS NEW BUILDING,
IT'S CHALK HILL MIDDLE SCHOOL,
THEY'RE CONVERTING ENTITLE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AND WE HAVE A PICTURE TO SHOW
OUR VIEWERS WHAT THEY'RE DOING
AND THE PROGRESS THEY'RE MAKING.
THEY'RE REPLICATING THE SANDY
HOOK CLASSROOMS DOWN TO THE
DESKS THAT THE STUDENTS HAD AT
SANDY HOOK, EVEN DOWN TO THE
CRAYON BOXES AND THE MATERIALS
THEY HAD IN THE DESKS AT THE
TIME.
AND WE'RE SHOWING THAT PICTURE
TO REALLY SHOW THE PROGRESS THAT
THEY ARE MAKING.
WE SPOKE WITH A FIRE MARSHAL
WOLF, TODAY AND HE SAID MONROE
WILL BE READY TO HAND OVER THE
BUILDING TO NEWTOWN OFFICIALS
LATER THIS WEEK.
AND OF COURSE, WHEN STUDENTS DO
RETURN TO THIS NEW BUILDING TO
START BACK, THE NEW SANDY HOOK,
IS WHAT WE CAN CALL IT, THEY CAN
REST ASSURED THIS WILL BE ONE OF
THE MOST SECURED SCHOOLS IN THE
STATE, AT THE VERY LEAST,
BECAUSE THEY WILL HAVE POLICE
BOTH INSIDE AND OUT.
>> AND IT'S ONLY ABOUT SEVEN
MILES AWAY FROM HERE?
>> IT'S A SHORT DISTANCE.
IT'S A SCHOOL THAT HAD BEEN
CLOSED LAST YEAR, DUE TO
DECLINING ENROLLMENT IN THAT
TOWN.
PEOPLE CALL IT A GODSEND THAT
THEY HAD THIS BUILDING REALLY
READY TO GO AND THEY'RE JUST
UPGRADING THINGS THAT THEY NEED
TO GET READY FOR AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
>> AND WE'RE TALKING NEARLY 600
KIDS, GRADES KINDERGARTEN
THROUGH FOURTH GRADE, WHO HAD
ATTENDED THE SANDY HOOK.
>> AND IT'S ABSOLUTELY FINE.
THIS FACILITY, I BELIEVE THEY
TOLD ME IT FITS 700 STUDENTS IN
THIS FACILITY.
THEY CAN EASILY FIT IN THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL STUDENTS.
AS SOON AS THE FIRE MARSHAL
SIGNS OFF ON THE NEW SECURITY
SYSTEMS, THE DOOR LOCKS, FIRE
ALARMS, SPRINKLERS, THAT KIND OF
THING.
>> GOOD INFORMATION.
WE WISH ALL THESE STUDENTS THE
BEST AND THEIR PARENTS AS WELL.
NOW LET'S SEE HOW THAT FIRST DAY
BACK AT SCHOOL WENT FOR A LOT OF
THESE STUDENTS HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
CNN'S MARY SNOW HAS BEEN
COVERING THIS PART OF THE STORY
FOR US.
MARY, UPDATE OUR VIEWERS.
>> Reporter: AND YOU KNOW, WOLF,
IN TALKING ABOUT THE EFFORTS TO
OPEN THAT NEW SCHOOL FOR THE
SANDY HOOK STUDENTS, WE'VE SEEN
TRUCKS MOVING THOUGH SUPPLIES,
BUT THERE WERE ABOUT 5,500
STUDENTS IN THIS SCHOOL
DISTRICT.
AND TODAY THE DISTRICT OPENED
ITS DOORS, SCHOOLS OPENED THEIR
DOORS FOR THE FIRST TIME SINCE
FRIDAY'S TRAGEDY.
SCHOOL BUSES ROLLING ONCE AGAIN,
AS NEWTOWN STRUGGLES TO RESUME A
SENSE OF NORMALCY.
BUT IT IS ANYTHING BUT NORMAL.
FUNERALS WERE HELD NEARBY.
POLICE PRESENCE WAS STEPPED UP.
CAMERAS FIXED ON THIS
GRIEF-STRICKEN TOWN.
IN THE MIDST OF IT, SOME PARENTS
WELCOMED GETTING BACK TO A
ROUTINE IN THE CLASSROOM.
>> IT'S EXACTLY WHAT THE KIDS
NEED AFTER SUCH A, YOU KNOW, A
TERRIBLE TRAGEDY.
A LOT OF THEM DO KNOW WHAT'S
GOING ON, AND THEY NEED
SOMEWHERE TO, YOU KNOW, GET
THEIR THOUGHTS --
>> CAN WE GO INSIDE NOW?
>> -- BACK TO THE FUN STUFF.
>> Reporter: BUT IT ALSO MEANT
THAT OTHER STUDENTS WHO HAD BEEN
SHIELDED BY WHAT HAPPENED WILL
NOW RETURN AND PERHAPS HEAR
ABOUT THE GRIM EVENTS THAT
HAPPENED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> WHEN I PICKED MY DAUGHTER UP
FROM SCHOOL ON FRIDAY, THE FIRST
WORDS OUT OF HER MOUTH WERE, PA,
WHY ARE YOU PICKING ME UP?
WE WERE HAVING SUCH A GREAT DAY.
AND I NEED TO THANK THE TEACHERS
AND THE STAFF FOR DOING THEIR
BEST TO SHIELD MY CHILD FROM
WHAT HAPPENED.
>> BEFORE RETURNING TO CLASS,
SCHOOLS ENCOURAGE PARENTS TO
TALK WITH THEIR KIDS ABOUT
FRIDAY'S HORRIFIC SHOOTINGS,
SAYING THE STAFF CAN'T CONTROL
WHAT CHILDREN HEAR FROM OTHERS.
>> WHEN A CRISIS LIKE THIS
HAPPENS --
>> Reporter: WENDY DAVENSON IS A
GRIEF COUNSELOR IN NEWTOWN WHO'S
BEEN ADVISING PARENTS ON HOW TO
TALK TO THEIR KIDS.
>> CHILDREN DON'T NEED DETAILS.
ALL THEY NEED TO KNOW IS A FACT.
THAT A BAD THING HAPPENED,
PEOPLE WERE KILLED, AND WE ARE
MAKING OUR SCHOOLS VERY SAFE AND
THIS DOESN'T HAPPEN VERY, VERY
OFTEN, AND WE ARE WORKING THAT
IT NEVER WILL HAPPEN AGAIN.
>> Reporter: AND TO PREPARE FOR
STUDENTS RETURNING, THE DISTRICT
MET WITH SCHOOL STAFF FROM BUS
DRIVERS TO TEACHERS ON MONDAY.
A CRISIS INTERVENTION EXPERT
SPOKE TO THEM.
AMONG THE THINGS HE CAUTIONED
ABOUT, THE DANGERS OF GETTING
TOO EMOTIONAL IN FRONT OF
CHILDREN.
SOMETHING DAVENSON SAYS CAN BE
OVERWHELMING FOR THE KIDS.
>> THAT'S TERRIFYING FOR
CHILDREN, BECAUSE WE ARE
SUPPOSED TO BE THE STRENGTH FOR
THEM.
WE PROVIDE SECURITY AND SAFETY
AND PREDICTABILITY.
AND IF THE TEACHERS FALL APART,
THAT'S GOING TO SCARE THEM.
>> Reporter: AND WOLF, AS YOU
CAN IMAGINE, THE COUNSELORS ARE
ON HAND FOR STUDENTS, STAFF, AND
ALSO PARENTS.
WOLF?
>> Reporter: MARY, THANKS VERY
MUCH, MARY SNOW, REPORTING.
>> THANK YOU, MARY.
>>> STILL AHEAD, THE WHITE HOUSE
IS GETTING SPECIFIC FOR THE
FIRST TIME ABOUT THE PRESIDENT'S
PROMISE TO DO SOMETHING ABOUT
GUN VIOLENCE.
ALSO, A LOVING TRIBUTE TO A
SUBSTITUTE TEACHER WHO DIED
DOING WHAT SHE LOVED.
LAUREN RUSSEAU'S BOYFRIEND
SHARES HER MEMORIES.
>>> AFTER THIS HORRIBLE TRAGEDY,
CALLS FOR CHANGES TO GUN CONTROL
LAWS.
THEY ARE CERTAINLY GROWING
LOUDER AND LOUDER.
AND UNTIL JUST A FEW HOURS AGO,
THE NATIONAL RIFLE ASSOCIATION
HAD BEEN LARGELY SILENT SINCE
FRIDAY MORNING.
BUT IN A STATEMENT THIS
AFTERNOON, THE GROUP NOW SAYS
THIS -- "OUT OF RESPECT FOR THE
FAMILIES AND AS A MATTER OF
COMMON DECENCY, WE HAVE GIVEN
TIME FOR MOURNING, PRAYER, AND A
FULL INVESTIGATION OF THE FACTS
BEFORE COMMENTING.
THE NRA IS PREPARED TO OFFER
MEANINGFUL CONTRIBUTIONS TO HELP
MAKE SURE THIS NEVER HAPPENS
AGAIN."
THAT STATEMENT FROM THE NRA AND
THEY SAY THEY'LL HAVE A
FULL-SCALE NEWS CONFERENCE
FRIDAY.
>> THE NRA WILL BE HOLDING A
NEWS CONFERENCE ON FRIDAY, AS
WOLF SAYS.
AND NO DOUBT THE STAUNCHLY
ANTI-GUN CONTROL GROUP WILL TRY
TO MAKE ITS VOICE HEARD BY
LAWMAKERS.
BEFORE LAST WEEK'S APPALLING
VIOLENCE HEAR IN NEWTOWN, GUN
CONTROL WAS ON ALMOST REALLY NO
ONE'S AGENDA IN WASHINGTON, BUT
THAT MIGHT BE CHANGING AT THIS
POINT.
CNN'S WHITE HOUSE CORRESPONDENT,
BRIANNA KEILAR HAS BEEN LOOKING
INTO THIS.
SO BRIANNA, WE HAVE HEARD TALK
OF GUN CONTROL MEASURES BEFORE.
WHAT'S DIFFERENT THIS TIME
AROUND?
>> Reporter: THE SENSE, KATE, IS
THAT THIS IS DIFFERENT.
PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS BEEN
CRITICIZED NOW FOR DAYS, BECAUSE
OF GUN CONTROL ADVOCATES FOR
BEING TOO VAGUE ABOUT HOW HE
WANTS TO TACKLE THIS PROBLEM.
NOW THE WHITE HOUSE IS DETAILING
SOME OF THE THINGS THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA WANTS TO DO.
TODAY, FOR THE FIRST TIME, THE
WHITE HOUSE GOT SPECIFIC ON HOW
THE PRESIDENT WILL TACKLE GUN
VIOLENCE.
>> IS HE RIGHT NOW ACTIVELY
CONSIDERING MEASURES, BE IT GUN
LAWS OR MENTAL HEALTH MEASURES,
RIGHT NOW?
>> WELL, HE IS ACTIVELY
SUPPORTIVE OF, FOR EXAMPLE,
SENATOR FEINSTEIN'S STATED
INTENT TO REVIVE A PIECE OF
LEGISLATION THAT WOULD REINSTATE
THE ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN.
>> Reporter: THE WHITE HOUSE
SAYS THE PRESIDENT WOULD ALSO
LIKE TO CLOSE THE GUN SHOW
LOOPHOLE, BAN HIGH-CAPACITY
AMMUNITION CLIP, AND LOOK AT
MEASURES THAT ADDRESS MENTAL
HEALTH.
CRITICS HAVE CHARGED THE
PRESIDENT WITH FAILING TO LEAD
ON GUN VIOLENCE, EVEN AS
REPUBLICAN SUPPORTERS OF GUN
RIGHTS, LIKE OHIO CONGRESSMAN,
STEVE LaTOURETTE, SAY IT'S TIME
TO FIND A BIPARTISAN SOLUTION.
>> I THINK MOST REPUBLICANS ARE
WILLING TO HAVE A VERY SERIOUS
CONVERSATION ABOUT WHAT THIS
MEANS AND THEY'RE TAKING A
SECOND LOOK AT WHAT THE SECOND
AMENDMENT MEANS IN THE 21st
CENTURY.
>> Reporter: DID THE PRESIDENT
FEEL LIKE HE WAS BEHIND ALL OF
THIS?
>> I THINK YOU'RE TRYING TO TURN
THIS INTO LIKE A POLITICAL
THEATER THING.
IT'S NOT HOW THE PRESIDENT VIEWS
IT.
>> BUT THE PRESIDENT IS
APPEARING TO ACT MORE
AGGRESSIVELY ON THE ISSUE.
HE CALLED WEST VIRGINIA SENATOR
JOE MANCHIN, A PRO-GUN RIGHTS
DEMOCRAT, WHO ONCE SHOWED IN HIS
OWN CAMPAIGN AD, SHOOTING THE
CAP AND TRADE BILL PUSHED BY
PRESIDENT OBAMA.
>> I'LL TAKE DEAD AIM AT THE CAP
AND TRADE BILL.
>> Reporter: HE NOW SAYS IT'S
TIME TO ACT ON GUN VIOLENCE.
THE PRESIDENT MET WITH MEMBERS
OF HIS CABINET MONDAY AFTERNOON.
VICE PRESIDENT JOE BIDEN,
EDUCATION SECRETARY, ARNE DUN  N
DUNCAN, HEALTH AND ASSUME
SERVICES SECRETARY, KATHLEEN
SEBELIUS, AND ERIC HOLDER, A
DEMONSTRATION OF THE
COMPREHENSIVE APPROACH THE
PRESIDENT WANTS TO TAKE IN
COMBATTING THE PROBLEM.
OBSERVERS OF THIS DEBATE SAY
PRESIDENT OBAMA COULD EXERT HIS
EXECUTIVE AUTHORITY AND BYPASS
CONGRESS TO GO IT ALONE ON
CERTAIN THINGS LIKE BETTER
SHARING OF INFORMATION BETWEEN
FEDERAL, STATE, AND LOCAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT ON POTENTIALLY
ILLEGAL GUN SALES.
THINGS LIKE RESTRICTING THE SALE
OF CERTAIN MILITARY-STYLE
WEAPONS, WOLF.
OF COURSE, THE ASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN, THAT IS SOMETHING THAT HE
WOULD NEED TO COOPERATE WITH
CONGRESS ON, WOLF.
>> BRIANNA KEILAR OVER AT THE
WHITE HOUSE, THANKS VERY MUCH
FOR THAT REPORT.
BY THE WAY, A CONNECTICUT
CONGRESSMAN WHO WAS JUST ELECTED
TO THE UNITED STATES SENATE IS
VERY EMOTIONAL ABOUT THIS
MASSACRE IN HIS DISTRICT.
THAT'S UNDERSTANDABLE.
HE'S STANDING BY TO TALK WITH
US.
WE'LL SPEAK WITH HIM WHEN WE
COME BACK.
TREES,
LIKE OUR TENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
>>> CONNECTICUT'S CONGRESSIONAL
DELEGATIONS SPONSORED A VIGIL, A
VIGIL FOR THE VICTIMS HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
ALSO, DEMOCRATIC REPRESENTATIVE
CHRIS MURPHY WENT TO THE FLOOR
OF THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES
TO GIVE AN EMOTIONAL SPEECH,
THANKING HIS COLLEAGUES FOR
THEIR SUPPORT AND PRAISING THE
PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN.
>> THE CLOSENESS OF NEWTOWN
MAKES IT HURT MORE, BUT THE
CLOSENESS OF NEWTOWN WILL ALSO
MAKE US HEAL AS WELL.
>> CONGRESSMAN MURPHY IS JOINING
US FROM WASHINGTON RIGHT NOW.
HE'LL BE LEAVING THE HOUSE NEXT
YEAR TO TAKE UP HIS NEW JOB AS A
JUST SENATOR FROM CONNECTICUT.
AND AS YOU JUST TOLD US,
SENATOR-ELECT, YOU'LL ALSO BE
HEADING BACK HERE TO CONNECTICUT
VERY SOON TO GRIEVE WITH MANY
FOLKS HERE.
THANKS FOR TAKING THE TIME TO BE
WITHES YOU.
>> WELL, THANKS FOR BEING THERE.
>> GO AHEAD.
>> HOW DO YOU THINK YOUR
COMMUNITY HERE, AND I KNOW YOUR
CONGRESSIONAL DISTRICT
REPRESENTS THE COMMUNITY HERE IN
NEWTOWN, HOW DO YOU THINK
THEY'RE HOLDING UP?
>> WELL, LISTEN, I THINK THERE'S
BEEN A BLANKNESS TO A LOT OF THE
FACES IN NEWTOWN.
YOU'VE SEEN IT.
PEOPLE ARE JUST TRYING TO
UNDERSTAND THIS.
THAT BEING SAID, YOU KNOW,
THERE'S SO MANY RESOURCES THAT
HAVE COME TO TOWN, WHETHER IT BE
GRIEF COUNSELORS OR PEOPLE TO
HELP GET THE STUDENTS BACK TO
SCHOOL.
I MEAN, PEOPLE DO FEEL A SENSE
OF LOVE COMING FROM CONNECTICUT,
COMING FROM THEIR COMMUNITY AND
COMING FROM THE WHOLE NATION AND
I HOPE THEY FELT A LITTLE BIT OF
THAT LAST NIGHT WHEN THE HOUSE
OF REPRESENTATIVES STOPPED TO
HONOR THE VICTIMS.
BUT THIS IS GOING TO BE A VERY
LONG PROCESS.
I WAS AT THE FIRST FUNERAL OF SO
MANY ON MONDAY, AND THE LITTLE
TWIN SISTER OF NOAH POZNER
HASN'T QUITE GRASPED YET THAT
SHE HAD LOST HER BROTHER.
AND YOU IMAGINE THAT OVER THE
COMING WEEKS AND MONTHS, THERE
ARE GOING TO BE PEOPLE WHO
FINALLY START TO REALIZE THIS
HURT.
EVEN WHEN THE TV CAMERAS LEAVE
NEWTOWN, WE'RE GOING TO NEED A
LOT OF HELP AND A LOT OF SUPPORT
TO HELP PEOPLE WHO ARE GOING TO
BE GRIEVING OVER A VERY LONG
TIME.
>> I KNOW YOU WERE BEING BRIEFED
ON THE INVESTIGATION.
DO YOU HAVE A BETTER SENSE OF
WHY THIS SHOOTER, THIS KILLER,
WENT TO THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL?
>> I DON'T.
I'M LEARNING AT THE SAME TIME
THAT EVERYONE ELSE IS.
AND I THINK A LOT OF PEOPLE IN
SANDY HOOK ARE ASKING THOSE
QUESTIONS OF WHY.
AND SOME PEOPLE HAVE ASKED THE
STATE POLICE, WELL, WHY ARE YOU
SPENDING SO MUCH TIME ON THE
MOTIVE IF YOU ALREADY KNOW WHO
THE KILLER IS?
YOU'RE NOT PREPARING FOR A
TRIAL.
BUT PEOPLE WANT TO GET AS MUCH
INFORMATION HERE AS THEY CAN.
THEY'RE NOT GOING TO GET ANSWERS
TO ALL OF THESE WHYS, BUT IF WE
CAN GET A LITTLE BIT BETTER VIEW
INTO THIS MOTIVE, I THINK IT
WILL ALLOW PEOPLE TO REST A
LITTLE BIT EASIER HAVING ALL
THAT INFORMATION AT THEIR
FINGERTIPS, IF IT EXISTS.
>> I WANT TO READ YOU A LETTER
THAT ONE OF YOUR CONSTITUENTS
SENT TO YOU, AS WELL AS TO
SENATOR BLUMENTHAL.
HE'S ALSO THE NEIGHBOR OF THE
SHOOTING VICTIM, ANN MARIE
MURPHY.
IN PART, HE WROTE THIS TO YOU IN
THE LETTER.
HE SAID, "THE PEOPLE OF YOUR
STATE HAVE BEEN ASSAULTED AND
MURDERED.
WE DEMAND THAT YOU TAKE
LEADERSHIP IN PURSUING NEW GUN
CONTROL LEGISLATION.
BE THE LEADER THAT THIS COUNTRY
IS SORELY LACKING.
HAVE THE COURAGE TO STAND UP FOR
THOSE KIDS THAT WERE MURDERED."
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO HIM?
WHAT HAS THIS TRAGEDY -- HOW HAS
THIS TRAGEDY CHANGED YOUR VIEWS?
>> I SAY THIS, THAT MY
PRIORITIES AS CONNECTICUT'S NEXT
U.S. SENATOR CHANGED ON FRIDAY.
I AM NOW GOING TO SPEND MY TIME
AS CONNECTICUT'S NEWEST U.S.
SENATOR LEADING THE FIGHT TO
COMBAT GUN VIOLENCE.
I'M GOING TO BE STANDING WITH
DIANNE FEINSTEIN AND WITH JOE
MANCHIN AND WITH MARK WARNER TO
PASS AN ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN.
I'M GOING TO BE LEADING A
CONVERSATION ABOUT HOW WE COMBAT
THE RISING CULTURE OF VIOLENCE
IN THIS COUNTRY.
YOU KNOW, MY TENURE AS A UNITED
STATES SENATOR FROM CONNECTICUT
CHANGED ON FRIDAY AND I'M GOING
TO ANSWER THAT CALL.
RIGHT NOW, I'M SPENDING MOST OF
MY TIME WITH MY CONSTITUENTS IN
NEWTOWN, GRIEVING.
BUT I AM GOING TO BE A LEADER TO
MAKE SURE THAT THE MEMORIES OF
THOSE 26 PEOPLE DO NOT GO ON IN
VAIN.
THAT THEY HAVE A SENATOR AND
THAT THEY HAVE PEOPLE IN
WASHINGTON WHO ARE GOING TO MAKE
SURE THAT WE DO EVERYTHING
WITHIN OUR POWER TO MAKE SURE
THAT THIS DOESN'T BEFALL ANY
OTHER COMMUNITY, ANYWHERE ELSE
IN THIS COUNTRY.
>> YOU KNOW, THERE HAVE BEEN A
FEW REPUBLICAN GOVERNORS, BOB
McDONNELL OF VIRGINIA, FOR
EXAMPLE, CONGRESSMAN, WHO
FLOATED THE IDEA THAT SCHOOL
OFFICIALS, PERHAPS, SHOULD BE
ARMED.
AND NOT JUST POLICE OFFICERS WHO
MAY BE AT SCHOOLS, BUT SCHOOL
OFFICIALS.
IS THAT A GOOD IDEA?
>> IT'S A RIDICULOUS NOTION.
THE FACT IS THAT NEWTOWN DID
EVERYTHING RIGHT.
THEY HAD PREPARED FOR EMERGENCY
DRILLS.
THEY EXECUTED THEM WITH
PERFECTION.
THEY HAD A SECURITY SYSTEM, THAT
FRANKLY WASN'T GOING TO HOLD UP
AGAINST SOMEONE WITH THAT KIND
OF WEAPONRY.
OUR FOCUS SHOULD BE ON KEEPING
THESE KIND OF DANGEROUS ASSAULT
WEAPONS OUT OF HIS HANDS.
MAKING SURE THAT NOBODY CAN WALK
IN WITH 30 ROUNDS IN A CLIP AND
TRYING TO PREVENT THE TRAGEDY IN
THE FIRST PLACE.
THE ANSWER IS NOT TO ARM AMERICA
AND ARM AMERICA'S SCHOOLS.
THE ANSWER IS TO TRY TO GET THE
GUNS OUT OF THE HANDS OF PEOPLE
WHO WOULD DO THIS KIND OF
VIOLENCE.
WE'VE GOT TO LOOK IN A TOTALLY
DIFFERENT DIRECTION THAN WHERE
SOME OF THESE PEOPLE ARE TRYING
TO POINT OUS.
>> CONGRESSMAN MURPHY, THANKS SO
MUCH FOR JOINING US.
GOOD LUCK.
THIS IS GOING TO BE A TOUGH
ASSIGNMENT FOR YOU AND A TOUGH
ASSIGNMENT FOR EVERYONE HERE.
I THINK I SPEAK FOR ALL OF US.
WE'VE BEEN THOROUGHLY IMPRESSED
BY THE PEOPLE IN NEWTOWN WHO
COULD NOT HAVE BEEN WARMER AND
MORE WELCOMING AND HAVE BEEN
EXCELLENT IN DEALING WITH THE
ENORMITY OF THIS CRISIS.
CONGRESSMAN AND SENATOR, THANKS
VERY MUCH.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>>> STILL AHEAD, AS NEWTOWN
BURIES SOME OF ITS CHILDREN, A
GLIMPSE AT THE HARD ROAD AHEAD
FROM PARENTS WHO LOST SONS AND
DAUGHTERS IN OTHER MASS
KILLINGS.
>>> JUST GOING TO A FRIEND'S
WEDDING AND WATCHING HER DANCE
WITH HER FATHER, THERE'S NO WAY
TO STOP THE TEARS.
>> TO KNOW WHAT WE'RE NEVER
GOING TO HAVE THOSE SIMPLE JOYS,
EVER AGAIN.
STS CELL HEALTH
PLAYS A KEY ROLE
THROUGHOUT OUR LIVES.
One A Day Men's 50+
IS A COMPLETE MULTIVITAMIN
DESIGNED FOR MEN'S HEALTH
CONCERNS AS WE AGE.
IT HAS 7 ANTIOXIDANTS
TO SUPPORT CELL HEALTH.
One A Day Men's 50+.
Progresso.
In what world do potatoes,
bacon and cheese
add up to 100 calories?
Your world.
♪
[ whispers ]
Real bacon...
Creamy cheese...
100 calories...
[ Chef ] Ma'am
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
AWW MAN.
[ Male Announcer ] RETURNS
ARE EASY WITH FREE PICKUP
FROM THE U.S. POSTAL SERVICE.
WE'LL EVEN DROP OFF BOXES
IF YOU NEED THEM.
VISIT USPS.COM
PAY, PRINT,
AND HAVE IT PICKED UP FOR FREE.
ANY TIME OF YEAR.
♪
NICE SWEATER.
THANK YOU.
♪
>>> THE TRAGEDY HERE IN NEWTOWN
HITS PAINFULLY CLOSE TO HOME FOR
SO MANY FAMILIES SCARRED BY
OTHER MASS SHOOTINGS.
SOME OF THEM WENT TO WASHINGTON
TODAY TO TRY TO HELP PUSH FOR
NEW GUN LAWS.
LISA SYLVESTER IS PICKI INING U
THIS PART OF THE STORY.
LISA?
>> WOLF, THESE FAMILIES, THEY
ALL HAVE A MESSAGE.
THEY HAVE BEEN THROUGH HELL AND
THEY WANT GUN VIOLENCE TO STOP.
ONE DAD WHO LOST HIS SON IN
COLUMBINE WORE THE VERY SHOES
HIS SON WAS WEARING THAT DAY.
OTHERS BROUGHT PICTURES OF THEIR
LOVED ONES AND THEY ALL HAVE
THEIR OWN DEEPLY HEARTBREAKING
STORIES.
>> I'M THE FATHER OF DANIEL
MAUSER, WHO WAS KILLED IN THE
MASSACRE AT COLUMBINE HIGH
SCHOOL.
>> MY SISTER WAS A FRESHMAN AT
VIRGINIA TECH.
SHE FOLLOWED ME THERE.
>> OUR DAUGHTER, JESSICA
REDFIELD GHAWI WAS KILLED IN
AURORA ON JULY 20th OF THIS
YEAR.
>> Reporter: A CLUB NO ONE
WANTED TO JOIN.
EACH ONE DIRECTLY TOUCHED BY GUN
VIOLENCE.
COLUMBINE, AURORA, VIRGINIA
TECH, TUCSON.
PETER REID'S DAUGHTER WAS A
FRESHMAN AT VIRGINIA TECH.
>> GOD FORGIVE US AS A COUNTRY
IF IT TAKES A LITERAL SLAUGHTER
OF INNOCENTS IN A HOLY SEASON TO
WAKE US UP.
>> Reporter: THE SLAYING OF
6-YEAR-OLDS AND 7-YEAR-OLDS IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, HAS BEEN
DESCRIBED AS A GAME CHANGER IN
THE DEBATE OVER GUN CONTROL.
THE BRADY CAMPAIGN TO PREVENT
GUN VIOLENCE INVITED FAMILIES TO
WASHINGTON TO PRESS CONGRESS TO
RENEW THE BAN ON ASSAULT WEAPONS
AND PASS OTHER GUN CONTROL
MEASURES.
>> THE ONLY PLACE THAT THIS IS A
CONTENTIOUS POLITICAL DEBATE IS
IN THAT BUILDING BEHIND US.
AND THERE'S A DISCONNECT BETWEEN
WHAT THE AMERICAN PUBLIC WANTS
ON THIS ISSUE AND WHAT OUR
ELECTELECT
ED OFFICIALS ARE DOING ABOUT IT.
>> Reporter: THE NATIONAL RIFLE
ASSOCIATION PUT OUT A STATEMENT
SAYING, "WE WERE SHOCKED,
SADDENED AND HEARTBROKEN BY THE
NEWS OF THE HORRIFIC AND
SENSELESS MURDERS IN NEWTOWN.
OUT OF RESPECT FOR THE FAMILIES
AND AS A MATTER OF COMMON
DECENCY, WE HAVE GIVEN TIME FOR
MOURNING, PRAYER, AND A FULL
INVESTIGATION OF THE FACTS
BEFORE COMMENTING."
THE NRA IS PREPARED TO OFFER
MEANINGFUL CONTRIBUTIONS TO HELP
MAKE SURE THIS NEVER HAPPENS
AGAIN.
FRIDAY MORNING, ANDRE PUT HIS
YOUNG SON, WHO HE CALLS BEAR, ON
THE SCHOOL BUS, HEADED FOR SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> HE WAS A CLASSROOM HELPER.
HE WAS SENT FROM HIS CLASSROOM
TO TURN IN ATTENDANCE SHEETS THE
TO THE PRINCIPAL'S OFFICE.
HE AND ANOTHER LITTLE KID.
TOGETHER THEY WENT INTO HALLWAY,
AND WHEN THEY WERE NEARING THE
PRINCIPAL, THE PRINCIPAL'S
OFFICE, THEY HEARD GUNSHOTS,
MISS CLEMENS, WHICH WHO WE'LL
EVER BE THANKFUL FOR AND WILL
NEVER BE ENOUGH, SHE PULLED THEM
IN HER OWN CLASSROOM AND
BARRICADED THE DOOR.
>> Reporter: HIS SON SURVIVED,
BUT 20 OTHER CHILDREN DID NOT.
>> WHY OUR POLITICIANS ARE NOT
DOING SOMETHING ABOUT THIS
PROBLEM?
I THINK THEY ARE TOO DEEP IN
THEIR PARTISAN BS.
>> JESSICA GHAWI DIED IN THE
AURORA MOVIE THEATER SHOOTING.
HER PARENTS SAY THEY FEEL A PAIN
THAT IS BEYOND WORDS.
>> JUST GOING TO HER FRIEND'S
WEDDING AND WATCHING HER DANCE
WITH HER FATHER, THERE'S NO WAY
TO STOP THE TEARS.
>> TO KNOW THAT WE'RE NEVER
GOING TO HAVE THOSE SIMPLE JOYS,
EVER AGAIN.
>> AND THOSE STORIES ARE SO,
INCREDIBLY HEARTBREAKING.
A NUMBER OF CONSERVATIVES IN
CONGRESS HAVE ALSO SAID, YOU
KNOW, MAYBE IT'S TIME WE TAKE A
LOOK AT THIS ISSUE AGAIN.
THE NATIONAL RIFLE ASSOCIATION
HAS BEEN LYING LOW FOR THE MOST
PART, SINCE THIS INCIDENT, BUT
THE NRA ANNOUNCED TODAY THAT IT
WILL HAVE A NEWS CONFERENCE ON
FRIDAY.
WOLF?
>> THANKS VERY MUCH, LISA, FOR
THAT REPORT.
TODAY, CONNECTICUT'S GOVERNOR
SIGNED A PROCLAMATION DECLARING
THIS COMING FRIDAY A DAY OF
MOURNING IN THE STATE.
HE'S REQUESTING THAT RESIDENTS
STATEWIDE PARTICIPANT IN A
MOMENT OF SILENCE AT 9:30 A.M.
THAT'S ABOUT THE SAME TIME THAT
ADAM LANZA SHOWED UP AT THE
SCHOOL AND STARTED SHOOTING.
TODAY, I SPOKE WITH A MAN WHO'S
BECOME THE PUBLIC FACE OF THE
INVESTIGATION, OF THE SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
LIEUTENANT, PAUL VANCE.
LIEUTENANT VANCE, IN YOUR
39-YEAR CAREER, HOW DO YOU
PREPARE FOR THE ENORMITY OF A
TRAGEDY LIKE THIS?
>> TRAINING.
TRAINING.
CONSTANT, CONSTANT TRAINING.
THINGS YOU HOPE YOU NEVER WILL
HAVE TO USE.
JUST LIKE THE SIDEARM THAT I
WEAR, YOU HOPE YOU'LL NEVER HAVE
TO USE IT.
YOU HAVE TO TRAIN, YOU HAVE TO
PREPARE.
BECAUSE WHEN YOU GET TO A SCENE
OR A SITUATION, EVEN A SCENE OF
THIS MAGNITUDE, YOU HAVE TO ACT.
AND THERE'S NO TIME.
>> BECAUSE YOU HAVE EMERGED AS
THE CHIEF SPOKESMAN.
YOU'RE TELLING NOT ONLY PEOPLE
HERE, BUT ALL OVER THE WORLD,
WHAT'S GOING ON.
IT MUST TAKE A TOLL ON YOU.
>> IT DOES.
BUT OUR TRAINING PREPARES US TO
WORK THROUGH THOSE ISSUES, TO GO
THROUGH SOMETHING LIKE THIS IS
DEVASTATING.
IT'S TRULY DEVASTATING, BECAUSE
WE'RE ONLY HUMAN.
AND WE THINK ABOUT THE FAMILIES,
WE THINK ABOUT THESE CHILDREN,
WE THINK ABOUT THE PEOPLE WHO
LOST THEIR LIVES.
WE THINK ABOUT THE TEACHERS THAT
PROTECTED THEIR CHILDREN.
AND ALL THOSE THINGS YOU
PROCESS, BUT YOU HAVE TO SHOVE
IT ASIDE AND MOVE FORWARD AND DO
WHAT YOU'RE TRAINED TO DO.
>> AND YOU MET WITH THESE
FAMILIES, OF THESE 26 VICTIMS,
20 KIDS, SIX EDUCATORS.
THAT MUST BE ONE OF THE MOST
DIFFICULT THINGS YOU'VE EVER
DONE IN YOUR LIFE.
>> I WAS PART OF IT, BUT QUITE
FRANKLY THE PEOPLE WHO WERE
ASSIGNED TO WORK WITH THEM, THE
ONE ON ONES, IF YOU WILL, THE
INTERVIEWERS THAT HAD TO
INTERVIEW PEOPLE, THOSE ARE
VERY, VERY HARD JOBS, ARE VERY
HARD THINGS TO DO.
THERE ARE SO MANY PEOPLE THAT
PLAYED SUCH A MAJOR ROLE IN THIS
WHOLE SITUATION, THAT IT'S
REALLY SPREAD OUT AMONGST MANY.
>> WAS THERE -- I KNOW THE WHOLE
THING HAS BEEN PAINFUL.
IT'S BEEN PACINFUL FOR ALL OF U
THAT HAVE BEEN HERE.
WAS THERE ONE MOMENT THAT STANDS
OUT IN YOUR MIND THAT YOU'LL
NEVER FORGET THE REST OF YOUR
LIFE?
>> I THINK THE CRIME SCENE
ITSELF IS SOMETHING THAT HAS
MADE AN INDELIBLE MARK IN ALL OF
OUR MINDS.
IF YOU WERE TASKED WITH THAT
RESPONSIBILITY OF GOING INTO
THAT CRIME SCENE, IT'S SOMETHING
THAT WE WILL NEVER BE ABLE TO
ERASE.
>> YOU MEAN, WHEN YOU WALKED
INTO THAT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AND YOU SAW THE BODIES OF
LITTLE KIDS ON THE FLOOR?
>> THAT'S RIGHT, YES.
>> HOW DO YOU -- HOW CAN YOU
EVEN -- THAT MUST BE SO
SHOCKING, THAT MUST BE SO
TRAUMATIC?
>> IT'S AN INDELIBLE MARK.
IT'S NEVER GOING TO GO AWAY.
>> YOU'VE NEVER SAW ANYTHING
LIKE THAT BEFORE IN YOUR LIFE?
>> NO.
>> I MEAN, YOU'VE BEEN TO A LOT
OF CRIME SCENES.
THIS WAS THE MOST HORRIFIC?
>> DEFINITELY.
>> BY FAR?
>> SO LET'S LOOK AHEAD NOW.
WE WANT TO MAKE SURE THIS
DOESN'T HAPPEN AGAIN.
IT WILL HAPPEN AGAIN.
YOU KNOW THAT.
I KNOW THAT.
WHAT CAN WE DO TO REDUCE THE
CHANCES OF THIS HAPPENING AGAIN?
>> WELL, I THINK EVERYONE'S
LOOKED AT THIS SCENE, THIS
SITUATION.
WE'VE ALWAYS PREPARED, EVEN WHEN
WE WERE YOUNGER, FOR FIRE
DRILLS.
WE PREPARED FOR EMERGENCIES
WITHIN THE SCHOOL.
I THINK THAT'S A CONSTANT THING
THAT WE'RE ALWAYS GOING TO DO IN
OUR EDUCATIONAL SYSTEM.
WE REVIEW, WE LOOK AT IT, WE
CONTINUE TO MAKE SURE HOW WE CAN
MAKE OUR MOST PRECIOUS CHILDREN
AS SAFE AS WE CAN MAKE THEM.
WE HAVE TO, WE WORKED THROUGH
9/11 AND WE CONTINUED AND LIFE
WENT ON.
I DON'T WANT TO SIMPLIFY
ANYTHING, BUT WE'VE GOT TO WORK
THROUGH THIS.
>> WE NEED A NATIONAL COMMISSION
TO TAKE A LOOK AT SCHOOL SAFETY?
>> THAT'S ABOVE ME.
THAT'S ABOVE ME.
I KNOW THAT ON A LOCAL LEVEL,
I'M SURE OUR TOWN LEADERS, OUR
STATE LEADERS ARE ALL GOING TO
CONTINUOUSLY LOOK AT SCHOOL
SAFETY TO ENSURE THAT OUR
CHILDREN ARE SAFE.
>> LIEUTENANT VANCE, LET ME
THANK YOU FOR WHAT YOU AND ALL
THE MEN AND WOMEN OF THE COUNTY
STATE POLICE HAVE DONE.
YOU'VE BEEN A SOURCE OF REAL
STRENGTH TO ALL OF US, AS
JOURNALISTS AND AS AMERICANS, AS
CITIZENS, IN LEARNING WHAT'S
GOING ON.
YOU'VE DONE AN OUTSTANDING JOB.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
APPRECIATE THAT.
>> THANK YOU.
>> HE HAS BEEN VERY STRONG AND
VERY MUCH THE FACE, THROUGHOUT
THIS ENTIRE ORDEAL.
>> I SPENT SOME QUALITY TIME
OVER AT THE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE HEADQUARTERS ABOUT 40
MINUTES OR SO FROM HERE.
A VERY DECENT GUY.
>> A VERY, VERY GOOD GUY.
>>> STAND BY FOR MORE OF OUR
COVERAGE ON THE CONNECTICUT
SHOOTING, AS WELL AS SOME OF THE
OTHER TOP STORIES TODAY,
INCLUDING A REPORTER'S HOSTAGE
ORDEAL IN SYRIA.
NBC'S RICHARD ENGLE IS SHARING
HIS STORY.
OK NYQUIL,
BUT I'M STILL "STUBBED" UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT DOESN'T HAVE A DECONGESTANT.
NO WAY.
[ Male Announcer ] SORRY.
Alka-Seltzer Plus FIGHTS
YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A FAST ACTING
DECONGESTANT
TO RELIEVE YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
[ sighs ] THANKS!
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus.
♪ OH
WHAT A RELIEF IT IS! ♪
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
AND SAVE $1
VISIT Alka-Seltzer ON FACEBOOK.
♪ BUT THE FIRE IS
SO DELIGHTFUL ♪
NOTHING MELTS AWAY THE COLD
LIKE A HOT, DELICIOUS BOWL
OF CHICKEN NOODLE SOUP
FROM CAMPBELL'S.
♪ LET IT SNOW, LET IT SNOW
>>> A TEAM OF NBC NEWS
JOURNALISTS IS FINALLY SAFE AND
FREE AFTER BEING HELD BY
KIDNAPPERS IN SYRIA.
IVAN WATSON HAS THE LATEST
DETAILS FROM TURKEY.
>> Reporter: WOLF, THE LOOKS ON
THE NBC NEWS TEAM SAY IT ALL.
THE LOOKS OF RELIEF, SMILES, AND
EXHAUSTION AS WELL AFTER A
HARROWING FIVE-DAY ORDEAL INSIDE
SYRIA, AFTER BEING KIDNAPPED BY
MEN ON A ROADSIDE, A GANG OF MEN
WITH GUNS, JUST ABOUT TEN
MINUTES' DRIVE INTO SYRIAN
TERRITORY LAST WEEK.
TAKE A LISTEN TO WHAT NBC NEWS
FOREIGN CORRESPONDENT RICHARD
ENGLE SAYS ABOUT HOW THEY WERE
TREATED DURING THIS TIME IN
CAPTIVITY.
>> THEY TOOK US TO A SERIES OF
SAFE HOUSES AND INTERROGATION
PLACES AND THEY KEPT US
BLINDFOLDED, BOUND.
WE WEREN'T PHYSICALLY BEATEN OR
TORTURED.
IT WAS A LOT OF PSYCHOLOGICAL
TORTURE.
THREATS OF BEING KILLED.
THEY MADE US CHOOSE WHICH ONE OF
US WOULD BE SHOT FIRST.
AND WHEN WE REFUSED, THERE WERE
MOCK SHOOTINGS.
THEY PRETENDED TO SHOOT GAZI
SEVERAL TIMES.
AND WHEN YOU ARE BIND FOLDED --
AND THEN THEY FIRE THE GUN UP IN
THE AIR, IT CAN BE VERY
TRAUMATIC EXPERIENCE.
>> WOLF, RICHARD ENGLE SAYS THAT
HE WAS BEING HELD BY A
PRO-GOVERNMENT SHIBAHA MILITIA
MADE UP OF MEN THAT HE AND HIS
OTHER CAPTIVES IDENTIFIED AS
SHIITE MUSLIMS WHO THREATENED TO
KILL THE MAJORITY IN THAT PART
OF SYRIA.
THEY WERE ALSO TRYING TO
EXCHANGE THE NBC NEWS TEAM FOR
CAPTIVE IRANIAN AND LEBANON
CITIZENS IN THE CUSTODY OF
SYRIAN REBELS.
THE ONLY WAY THAT THE NBC NEWS
TEAM ESCAPED WAS AFTER THEIR
CAPTORS RAN INTO A SYRIAN REBEL
CHECKPOINT LATE MONDAY NIGHT.
A GUN BATTLE ENSUED.
TWO OF THE KIDNAPPERS WERE
KILLED, AND THE SYRIAN REBELS
RESCUED THE NBC NEWS TEAM.
THEY ARE OUT, SAFE AND SOUND,
UNHARMED.
BUT THERE ARE MANY MORE PEOPLE
WHO ARE STILL MISSING INSIDE
SYRIA, WOLF.
IT HAS BEEN A PLAGUE OF
KIDNAPPING AND HOSTAGE TAKING
THERE.
THERE ARE NO LESS THAN 21
JOURNALISTS AND 18 OTHER CITIZEN
JOURNALISTS CURRENTLY MISSING,
ACCORDING TO THE ORGANIZATION
REPORTERS WITHOUT BORDERS.
MANY ORDINARY SYRIANS BEING HELD
FOR RANSOM AS LAW AND ORDER
CONTINUES TO BREAK DOWN IN THAT
WAR-TORN COUNTRY.
WOLF?
>> IVAN WATSON, THANKS VERY
MUCH.
AND IT UNDERSCORES, KATE, JUST
HOW DANGEROUS THESE ASSIGNMENTS
ARE.
YOU KNOW, SO HAPPY THAT THESE
NBC JOURNALISTS GOT OUT.
>> SO, SO THANKFUL THAT THEY GOT
OUT, WOLF.
YOU'RE SO RIGHT.
>>> OTHER STORIES THAT WE ARE
WATCHING TODAY.
ON CAPITOL HILL, A DEAL COULD BE
TAKING SHAPE TO AVOID THE FISCAL
CLIFF, NOW JUST TWO WEEKS AWAY.
OUR LISA SYLVESTER IS HERE WITH
THAT AND MORE OF TODAY'S TOP
STORIES.
HEY THERE, LISA.
>> HI, THERE, WOLF AND KATE.
WELL, AS AMERICANS EDGE EVER
CLOSER TO HUGE TAX HIKES AND
DEEP AUTOMATIC SPENDING CUTS,
BOTH SIDES ARE OFFERING
COMPROMISES TODAY.
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER
PROPOSED A SHORT-TERM PLAN,
HIGHER TAX RATES ON
MILLIONAIRES, BUT THE WHITE
HOUSE AND DEMOCRATIC LEADERS SAY
THAT DOESN'T GO FAR ENOUGH.
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS STANDING FIRM
ON HIGHER RATES FOR PEOPLE
EARNING MORE THAN $250,000 A
YEAR.
>>> AND THE WOMAN WHO HAD AN
AFFAIR WITH FORMER CIA DIRECTOR
DAVID PETRAEUS WILL NOT FACE
FEDERAL CYBERSTALKING CHARGES.
PAULA BROADWELL WAS UNDER
INVESTIGATION FOR SENDING
ALLEGEDLY HARASSING, ANONYMOUS
E-MAILS TO TAMPA SOCIALITE JILL
KELLY, A FRIEND OF PETRAEUS AND
HIS WIFE.
IN NOVEMBER, PETRAEUS RESIGNED
AS CIA DIRECTOR AFTER REVEALING
HIS AFFAIR.
SOURCES TELL CNN, THOUGH, THAT
BROADWELL STILL COULD FACE
CHARGES FOR POSSESSING
CLASSIFIED MATERIAL.
>>> AND THE PHOTO-SHARING
WEBSITE INSTAGRAM AND WARNING
USERS THAT STARTING NEXT YEAR,
IT MAY SELL PHOTOS TO OTHER
COMPANIES AND KEEP ALL OF THE
CASH.
THE CHANGE IN THE TERMS OF USE
EXPLAINS USERS WON'T BE
COMPENSATED IN ANY WAY.
USERS CANNOT OPT OUT OF THE NEW
PROVISIONS AND THE ONLY WAY TO
AVOID THEM IS TO DELETE YOUR
INSTAGRAM ACCOUNT ALTOGETHER.
>>> AND THERE IS GOOD NEWS AT
THE GAS PUMP AND IT MAY BE
GETTING EVEN BETTER.
THE AVERAGE PRICE OF REGULAR
SELF-SERVE GASOLINE IN THE U.S.
IS NOW $3.24 A GALLON.
THE PRICE HAS FALLEN EVERY DAY
FOR ALMOST A MONTH AND EXPERTS
SAY IT COULD FALL TO LEVELS NOT
SEEN IN TWO YEARS.
ANALYSTS CREDIT IN PART BETTER
FUEL ECONOMY AND MORE
TELECOMMUTING.
KATE AND WOLF?
>> THANKS SO MUCH, LISA.
>> THANKS VERY MUCH.
>>> AT CNN, WE'RE VERY CONCERNED
ABOUT RESPECTING THE PRIVACY OF
PEOPLE WHO LOST LOVED ONES HERE
IN NEWTOWN AND ARE VERY, VERY
CONCERNED ABOUT THAT.
BUT SOME RELATIVES AND FRIENDS
ARE EAGER TO SPEAK OUT AND TO
TALK, TO MAKE SURE THE WORLD
KNOWS WHO THESE VICTIMS WERE AND
WHY THEY WERE SO LOVED.
CNN'S ERIN BURNETT IS JOINING US
NOW WITH A LITTLE PREVIEW OF
WHAT YOU HAVE COMING UP IN THE
NEXT HOUR.
WHAT DO YOU HAVE, ERIN?
>> THERE ARE SOME PEOPLE WHO DO
WANT TO TALK.
AND AS YOU WELL KNOW, TALK ABOUT
THIS COMMUNITY AND HOW IT FEELS
AND HOW TIGHT-KNIT IT IS AND HOW
THEY DON'T WANT IT TO BECOME A
NAME THAT BECOMES SYNONYMOUS
WITH A HORRIBLE ACT.
WE'RE GOING TO BE TALKING WITH
ONE DAD WHO HAS FOUR KIDS.
A 4-YEAR-OLD, ACTUALLY, WHO'S
ABOUT TO GO TO SANDY HOOK NEXT
YEAR, AND HE IS DEAD SET THAT
THAT CHILD IS GOING TO GO TO
SANDY HOOK.
AND IT'S PRETTY AMAZING.
HE AND HIS WIFE MOVED HERE FROM
CALIFORNIA.
NUMBER ONE REASON, FOR THE
SCHOOLS.
HE'S GOING TO JOIN US TO TALK
ABOUT THAT.
HIS OLDER SONS WAS BROTHERS WITH
JACK PINTO'S BROTHER AND THEY
WERE AT THAT FUNERAL YESTERDAY.
THEY'RE GOING TO TALK ABOUT
THAT.
VICKIE SOTO WAS A TEACHER FOR
ONE OF HIS DAUGHTERS, SHE WAS A
SUBSTITUTE A FEW YEARS AGO WHEN
HIS DAUGHTER WAS THERE, BUT SO
MEMORABLE, THAT HER DAUGHTER
STILL REMEMBERS HER.
WE'LL BE TALKING WITH THEM, AND
ALSO WITH THE FAMILY WHO MOVED
HERE FROM NEWTOWN FROM
AUSTRALIA.
REASON NUMBER ONE, THEY THOUGHT
IT WAS THE SAFEST TOWN IN
AMERICA, REASON NUMBER TWO, FOR
SCHOOLS.
THEIR TWO BOYS JUST WENT BACK TO
SCHOOL TODAY AND THEIR WHOLE
FAMILY WILL BE WITH US AT THE
TOP OF THE HOUR.
SO A SPECIAL PROGRAM COMING UP.
>> WE'VE HEARD THIS MANY, MANY
TIMES, JUST HOW GREAT THE SCHOOL
SYSTEM IS HERE.
AND WILL CONTINUE TO BE, OF
COURSE, AFTER THIS.
>> YOU'VE BEEN DOING A GREAT JOB
WITH THESE PERSONAL STORIES,
ERIN.
WE'RE REALLY LOOKING FORWARD TO
THE NEXT HOUR.
THANKS SO MUCH FOR WHAT YOU'RE
DOING.
>> THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU, ERIN.
>>> A MOTHER WHOSE DAUGHTER DIED
IN HER FIRST GRADE CLASSROOM
DESCRIBES MEETING PRESIDENT
OBAMA.
WHAT SHE SHARED WITH THE
PRESIDENT AND WHAT SHE SAYS SHE
PRAYED FOR WITH HIM.
ANDERSON COOPER SAT DOWN WITH
HER.
HE'LL JOIN US LIVE.
THAT'S NEXT.
>>> CERTAINLY IMPOSSIBLE TO
IMAGINE THE PAIN OF SOME OF
THESE PARENTS HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, ARE FEELING RIGHT
NOW.
FACING THE FACT THAT THEY MUST
BURY THEIR 6-YEAR-OLD OR
7-YEAR-OLD CHILD.
OUR OWN ANDERSON COOPER IS HERE
FOR US ON THE SCENE.
ANDERSON, YOU SAT DOWN WITH THE
FAMILY OF GRACE McDONNELL AND
HAVE MORE OF THAT TOUCHING
INTERVIEW COMING UP.
SHARE SOME OF IT WITH OUR
VIEWERS.
>> Reporter: YOU KNOW, IT WAS
LYNN AND CHRIS McDONNELL.
THEIR DAUGHTER, GRACE, 7 YEARS
OLD, WAS KILLED ON FRIDAY.
THEY HAVE A SON, JACK, WHO'S 12
YEARS OLD.
AND THEY ACTUALLY CONTACTED US.
THEY REACHED OUT TO US THE OTHER
DAY AND ASKED US TO COME BY
THEIR HOME AND JUST SPEND SOME
TIME WITH THEM AND LEARN ABOUT
GRACE AND THEY WANTED A LOT OF
PEOPLE TO KNOW ABOUT THEIR
AMAZING GRACE.
AND SO WE'RE GOING TO BE
BRINGING YOU THAT EXTENSIVE
INTERVIEW TONIGHT ON "A.C. 360."
BUT I WANT TO PLAY YOU JUST A
LITTLE BIT OF WHAT THEY SAID.
THEY TALKED ABOUT MEETING
PRESIDENT OBAMA THE OTHER NIGHT.
AND GRACE WAS A PROLIFIC ARTIST.
SHE WAS, FOR 7 YEARS OLD, SHE
WAS INCREDIBLY TALENTED ARTIST.
AND SHE DREW A PICTURE OF AN OWL
AND THEY GAVE THAT PICTURE TO
THE PRESIDENT.
AND HE SAID HE WOULD CHERISH IT.
AND THAT REALLY GAVE THEM
COMFORT, THAT THE PRESIDENT
WOULD TAKE TIME TO LEARN ABOUT
THEIR DAUGHTER.
HERE'S MORE O OF WHAT THEY HAD
TO SAY.
>> IT WAS A VERY PRIVATE
MEETING, BUT WHEN HE WALKED IN
THE ROOM TO GREET US, IT WAS
JUST A DAD.
HE'S JUST A DAD, COMING IN TO
MEET A DAD AND A MOM AND A SON.
AND WE REALLY FELT THAT.
WE FELT HIS SUPPORT AND IT WAS
REALLY, IT WAS REALLY SPECIAL.
AND WE SHARED SOME SPECIAL
THINGS ABOUT GRACE WITH HIM AND
HER ART.
GRACE'S DREAM WAS TO LIVE ON THE
BEACH AND BE A PAINTER.
AND SO WE OFFERED HIM ONE OF HER
PAINTINGS, WHICH HE SAID HE
WOULD TREASURE.
SO THAT GAVE US GREAT COMFORT,
TOO.
BUT, REALLY, JUST FELT LIKE A
DAD SURROUNDING US AND FEELING
OUR PAIN.
AND YOU KNOW, WHEN HE WALKED IN
THE ROOM, I REALIZED, HE HAS TO
GO TO SO MANY FAMILIES TODAY,
AND THIS IS NOT THE FIRST TIME
HE'S HAD TO DO THIS.
SO, I HAVE TO LOOK AT HIM AND
PRAY FOR HIM FOR STRENGTH.
>> THEY, OF COURSE, WEREN'T ABLE
TO SEE GRACE IN THE WAKE OF THE
ATTACK.
THEY WERE ADVISED NOT TO VIEW
HER.
BUT WHEN THEY WENT IN TO VISIT
WITH HER AND THE CASKET, THE
CASKET WAS ALL WHITE, AND IT
REALLY BROUGHT HOME TO THEM THE
REALITY OF WHAT WAS HAPPENING.
AND THEY BROUGHT CRAYONS AND
MAGIC MARKERS, AND LYNN AND
CHRIS AND JACK DREW ALL OVER THE
CASKET.
AND THEY WANTED TO COLOR IT ALL,
AND ALL THE THINGS THAT GRACE
LOVED.
PEACE SIGNS AND FLIP-FLOPS, AND
REMINDERS OF HAWAII AND OTHER
PLACES THEY HAD VISITED.
AND THEY SAID BY THE TIME THEY
LEFT THE THE ENTIRE
CASKET WAS COLORED, AND THAT
ALSO HAS GIVEN THEM COMFORT AND
GRACE, THEY ARE GOING TO BE
REMEMBERING GRACE, A WAKE ON
THURSDAY, A FUNERAL ON FRIDAY.
BUT IT'S AMAZING HOW STRONG THEY
ARE AND WE'LL BE PLAYING MORE OF
THAT INTERVIEW TONIGHT, WOLF.
>> THEY REALLY REACHED OUT TO
YOU, ANDERSON, BECAUSE THEY WANT
THE WORLD TO KNOW HOW WONDERFUL
GRACE WAS.
THEY WANT TO SHARE THAT STORY
WITH EVERYONE.
AND IT'S NOT ALL THAT UNUSUAL,
BECAUSE A LOT OF TIMES PARENTS
WHO LOSE SOMEONE IN A SITUATION
LIKE THIS, I REMEMBER AT
VIRGINIA TECH, THEY WANT TO
SPEAK OUT AND EXPRESS HOW MUCH
THEY LOVED THEIR CHILD.
>> YOU KNOW, IT HELPS TO TALK.
IT HELPS TO TALK, IT HELPS LYNN
TO TALK AND IT HELPS CHRIS TO
TALK AND EVEN JACK, 12-YEAR-OLD
JACK, WHO OBVIOUSLY WE DIDN'T
INTERVIEW ON CAMERA, IT HELPS
HIM TO TALK ABOUT GRACE.
SO EVEN BEFORE WE SAT DOWN FOR
THE INTERVIEW, I SPENT A LOT OF
TIME THERE HONESTLY JUST HUGGING
AND HOLDING HANDS WITH THEM AND
JUST LOOKING AT ALL THE PICTURES
OF GRACE AND HEARING THE STORIES
ABOUT HER.
I THINK IT REALLY, IT DOES HELP
THEM TO TALK AND TO LET OTHER
PEOPLE KNOW ABOUT THEIR
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE GIRL.
>> EVERY ONE OF THESE STORIES WE
COVER, ANDERSON, IS UNIQUE AND
DISTINCTIVE.
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT YOU, BUT FOR
ME, I NEVER REALLY EXPERIENCED
ANYTHING LIKE THIS, BECAUSE
THESE 20 KIDS WERE 6 AND 7 YEARS
OLD, ALL OF THESE.
THE TEACHERS AND THEM, IT'S BEEN
SO POWERFUL, SO AWFUL FOR ME.
I'M SURE IT'S BEEN LIKE THAT FOR
YOU AS WELL.
>> I FEEL PRIVILEGED TO BE HERE.
I THINK THERE IS AN
EXTRAORDINARY SENSE OF THIS
COMMUNITY COMING TOGETHER,
EXTRAORDINARY SUPPORT FOR THESE
FAMILIES THAT ARE FACING THE
UNIMAGINABLE, AND YOU KNOW, IT'S
NOT JUST, WOLF, YOU KNOW, THIS
PAST WEEKEND AND TODAY AND THIS
WEEK, WHEN THE FUNERALS ARE
GOING TO BE TAKING PLACE.
A LOT OF THIS, WHEN THE MEDIA
LEAVES AND WHEN THE WORLD'S
ATTENTION KIND OF MOVES ON, LIFE
FOR PEOPLE HERE HAS STOPPED.
THE WORLD HAS STOPPED.
AND THOUGH THE REST OF THE WORLD
MAY KEEP SPINNING, IT WILL NOT
KEEP SPINNING HERE IN NEWTOWN.
I THINK FOR THESE FAMILIES,
THAT'S GOING TO BE ANOTHER
HURDLE WHEN THE ADRENALINE KIND
OF FADES AWAY AND THEY'RE LEFT
WITH JUST THE DAY-TO-DAY HORROR
OF THE REALITY OF THEIR LOVED
ONE NOT BEING WITH THEM.
>> SEE YOU IN A LITTLE MORE THAN
AN HOUR FROM NOW, ANDERSON.
THANKS SO MUCH FOR DOING THIS.
THANKS SO MUCH FOR WHAT YOU'VE
BEEN DOING.
>>> A POPULAR TV SHOW PAYS
TRIBUTE TO THE NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT VICTIMS.
THIS IS SOMETHING THAT IS VERY,
VERY MOVING.
WE'LL SHARE IT WITH YOU WHEN WE
COME BACK.
G SUCH A
GREAT YEAR IN THE GULF,
WE'VE DECIDED TO
PUT ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
'CAUSE ALL OUR STATES ARE GREAT.
AND NOW IS WHEN THE GULF
GETS EVEN BETTER.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE OR
JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
ENJOY THE WILDLIFE
AND NATURAL BEAUTY.
AND DON'T FORGET
OUR AMAZING SEAFOOD.
SO COME TO THE GULF,
YOU'LL HAVE A GREAT TIME.
ESPECIALLY IN ALABAMA.
YOU MEAN MISSISSIPPI.
THAT'S FLORIDA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP AND ALL
OF US WHO CALL THE GULF HOME.
PROGRESSIVE DIRECT AND OTHER
CAR INSURANCE COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
CALL OR CLICK TODAY.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME FOR CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
I'M GOING TO DREAM
ABOUT THAT STEAK.
ABOUT THAT TIRAMISU.
WHAT A NIGHT, HUH?
BUT, UM, CAN THE TEST DRIVE
BE OVER NOW?
HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A PASSAT.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN, $0 DUE AT SIGNING,
$0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
>>> YOUNG SURVIVORS OF THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING ARE GETTING
THERAPY AND THEY ARE GETTING
SOME COMFORT IN A RATHER UNUSUAL
WAY.
HERE'S CNN'S GARY TUCHMAN.
>> Reporter: NINE GOLDEN
RETRIEVERS ON THE MARCH.
MAKING THEIR WAY INTO A
RECREATION CENTER IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, FOR AN EMOTIONAL
RESCUE, TO HELP COMFORT THE
CHILDREN WHO SURVIVED THE ATTACK
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY AND
OTHER CHILDREN IN TOWN.
THERAPEUTIC CANINES WERE
SPONSORED AND TRAINED BY
LUTHERAN CHURCH CHARITIES,
TRANSPORTED IN A VAN FOR A 900
MILE RIDE FROM ILLINOIS.
LET ME GIVE YOU A QUICK
INTRODUCTION TO ALL THE DOGS
HERE.
THIS IS CHEWIE.
THIS IS RUTHIE.
ABBY.
PRINCE.
LUTHER.
MAGGIE.
HANNAH.
BARNEY.
AND SHAMMY.
THESE ARE THE COMFORT DOGS.
WHAT IS A COMFORT DOG?
>> A COMFORT DOG IS ONE WHO
BRINGS COMFORT TO OTHER PEOPLE.
WHEN THEY'RE SUFFERING OR
HURTING OR BRING HAPPINESS TO
PEOPLE, HELPS PEOPLE PROCESS
THEIR GRIEF.
>> Reporter: THEY ARE SPECIALLY
TRAINED?
>> THEY ARE SPECIALLY TRAINED.
THESE ARE ALL TRAINED SERVICE
DOGS.
WE DON'T USE THEM WITH DISABLED
BUT WE USE THAT TRAINING AND
THEN WE TRAIN THEM ADDITIONALLY
TO WORK WITH ALL DIFFERENT AGE
GROUPS AND PEOPLE.
TO SOME PEOPLE, WE HAVE SEEN
THIS WITH CHILDREN, IT BRINGS A
SENSE OF CALMNESS IN A TIME OF
CONFUSION FOR THEM, DURING THIS
PERIOD.
TO SOME, IT HELPS THEM PROCESS
THEIR GRIEF.
THEY'LL START CRYING AND THEY'LL
HUG THE DOG.
AND TO SOME CHILDREN, THEY'LL
COME UP SAD AND THEY'LL WALK
AWAY HAPPY.
>> Reporter: DO YOU KNOW THAT
LUTHER IS INCAPABLE OF BEING
MEAN.
LUTHER IS A FRIENDLY DOG.
>> HAYDEN LOVES DOGS.
>> Reporter: WHEN DOES TRAINING
BEGIN TO BE A COMFORT DOG?
>> FIVE AND A HALF WEEKS.
WE BUY PUPPIES AT FIVE AND A
HALF WEEKS, TURN THEM UPSIDE
DOWN --
>> Reporter: TURN THEM UPSIDE
DOWN.
IF THEY ARE TURNED UPSIDE DOWN
AND THEY FLAIL, THEY CAN'T BE A
COMFORT DOG?
>> RIGHT.
OUR INITIAL SCREENING IS IF THEY
CAN BE RELAXED IN THAT POSITION,
THEN WE START THE NEXT PROCESS
WHICH IS A TRAINER THAT WORKS
WITH THEM ONE-ON-ONE FOR THE
NEXT EIGHT MONTHS TO A YEAR.
>> Reporter: WHERE ELSE HAVE
YOUR DOGS BEEN?
WHAT OTHER DISASTERS?
>> OUR DOGS A MONTH AGO WHEN
SANDY HIT, WE WERE OUT IN NEW
YORK AND NEW JERSEY.
WE HAVE BEEN IN INDIANA WITH THE
FLOODINGS.
WE HAD DOGS OUT IN JOPLIN,
MISSOURI.
THIS IS LUTHER.
HE'S A COMFORT DOG.
YOU CAN PET HIM.
SAYS RIGHT HERE, PLEASE PET ME.
>> Reporter: HOW DO YOU FEEL
WHEN YOU SEE A CHILD COME UP TO
ONE OF YOUR DOGS WHO HAS BEEN IN
THIS KIND OF SITUATION, HAVE A
BIG SMILE ON THEIR FACE?
>> TEARS.
THEY SMILE, I CRY.
>> Reporter: AMID THE CONTINUING
SADNESS HERE, THERE WERE A LOT
OF SMILES.
>> WHAT A STORY.
ERIN BURNETT "OUTFRONT" STARTS
IN JUST A MOMENT.
BUT WE LEAVE YOU THIS HOUR WITH
THIS VERY POWERFUL MUSICAL
TRIBUTE TO THE VICTIMS, TRIBUTE
THAT AIRED ON THE NBC SHOW "THE
VOICE."
♪ I'VE HEARD THERE WAS A SECRET
CODE
THAT DAVID PLAYED AND IT PLEASED
THE LORD
BUT YOU DON'T REALLY CARE FOR
MUSIC DO YOU ♪
♪ IT GOES LIKE THIS
HALLELUJAH ♪
♪ HALLELUJAH
HALLELUJAH
HALLELUJAH ♪