AT 9:30 OR SO THIS MORNING,
SHOTS RANG OUT AS AT LEAST ONE
GUNMAN ENTERED THAT SCHOOL AND
THAT GUNMAN IS DEAD.
AS POLICE HAVE BEEN TELLING US
NOW, 20 CHILDREN DEAD, 18 OF
THEM DEAD AT THE SCENE.
AND IN ADDITION TO THAT, SIX
ADULTS ARE ALSO DEAD, INCLUDING
THE PRINCIPAL OF THE SCHOOL.
WE UNDERSTAND THAT YET ANOTHER
ADULT WAS FOUND DEAD AT ANOTHER
LOCATION THAT POLICE ARE NOT
OFFICIALLY DISCLOSING AS OF YET.
AND WE ARE TOLD THAT THE MOTHER
OF THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER, WHO IS
ALSO DEAD AT THE SCENE, WAS ALSO
KILLED.
SHE IS A TEACHER AND SHE WAS
ALSO KILLED AT THAT SCHOOL,
ACCORDING TO OUR LAW ENFORCEMENT
SOURCES.
IN ADDITION TO THIS, WE ARE ALSO
TOLD BY OUR SOURCES THAT ANOTHER
PERSON IS BEING QUESTIONED AT
THIS TIME BUT IS NOT BEING
CALLED A SUSPECT RIGHT NOW, AND
ALSO THAT PERSON IS NOT BEING
IDENTIFIED, WOLF.
SO WHILE THE SCHOOL IS BEING
CALLED SECURE AND SAFE BY LAW
ENFORCEMENT AUTHORITIES RIGHT
NOW, THEY ARE -- THEY STILL HAVE
A LOT OF INVESTIGATING TO DO.
THEY HAVE NOT OFFICIALLY
RELEASED THE NAME OF THE SHOOTER
OR THE OTHER PERSON BEING
QUESTIONED OR THE NAMES OF ANY
OF THE VICTIMS AT THIS TIME.
IT'S JUST AN AWFUL SCENE, AND
PARENTS FOUND OUT ABOUT THIS,
WOLF, WHEN THEY RECEIVED A LOT
OF THEM TEXT MESSAGES, ALERTS
FROM THE SCHOOL THAT HAD THEM
RUSHING OVER TO THE SCHOOL AS A
911 CALL CAME IN.
POLICE ARRIVED ON THE SCENE,
THEY TRIED TO SECURE THE SCENE
AND MAKE SURE THAT IT WAS SAFE
SO THAT ALL THE CHILDREN WERE
IMMEDIATELY EVACUATED FROM THE
SCHOOL AND BROUGHT TO A SAFE
LOCATION NEARBY WHERE THEY COULD
BE REUNITED WITH THEIR PARENTS.
WE KNOW THIS ONE THING FROM THE
SHOOTER.
WE UNDERSTAND THAT AT LEAST
THREE WEAPONS WERE FOUND AT THE
SCENE.
ONE OF THEM A GLOCK, ONE OF THEM
A SIG SAUER AND ONE OF THEM A
223 BUSHMASTER.
WE DON'T KNOW EXACTLY WHAT KIND
OF MODELS BUT WE HAVE THAT AS
WELL.
AND HERE'S MORE ABOUT HOW IT ALL
CAME DOWN FROM START TO FINISH.
THESE CONNECTICUT PARENTS HAD
DROPPED OFF THEIR KIDS FOR A
TYPICAL FRIDAY AT SCHOOL.
THEN ABOUT 9:30 IN THE MORNING,
THEY RECEIVED ROBO CALLS AND
TEXT MESSAGES.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WAS
PUT ON ALERT.
>> I JUST GOT A MESSAGE
SAYING -- FROM THE
SUPERINTENDENT THAT THERE WAS --
THERE WAS AN UNCONFIRMED
SHOOTING AND, YOU KNOW,
EVERYBODY IS IN LOCK DOWN.
>> I WAS A LITTLE SCARED.
I FELT SICK TO MY STOMACH.
>> Reporter: A GUNMAN WAS FIRING
AWAY AS TEACHERS WENT INTO
LOCKDOWN AND PARENTS RUSHED TO
THE SCENE.
>> I HEARD SCREAMING.
AND SO WE -- WE WENT -- LIKE WE
WENT TO THE WALL AND WE SAT DOWN
AND THEN POLICE CAME IN.
IT'S LIKE IS HE IN HERE?
THEN HE RAN OUT.
THEN OUR TEACHER -- THEN
SOMEBODY YELLED GET TO A SAFE
PLACE.
>> INSIDE, CHILDREN WERE HIDING
AS A GUNMAN FIRED AWAY.
>> THEY WERE CRYIN IN THE
CLOSET.
IN THE CLOSET OF THE ART ROOM.
AND EVENTUALLY, THEY WERE
LEAVING AND WHEN THEY WERE
LEAVING, THE POLICE MADE THEM
HOLD HANDS.
THE POLICE TOLD THEM TO CLOSE
THEIR EYES.
>> TOLD TO KEEP THEIR EYES
CLOSED BECAUSE A GUNMAN WAS ON A
KILLING SPREE, KILLING THE
PRINCIPAL, A COUNSELOR, CHILD
AFTER CHILD.
>> ON AND OFF DUTY TROOPERS
RESPONDED TO THE SCHOOL.
THAT INCLUDED CHECKING EVERY
DOOR, EVERY CRACK, EVERY
CREVICE, EVERY PORTION OF THAT
SCHOOL.
>> Reporter: AND AGAIN, OUR
UNDERSTANDING IS THAT ALL OF
THIS HAPPENED IN ONE PARTICULAR
AREA OF THE SCHOOL, JUST ONE
AREA OF THE SCHOOL WHERE ALL THE
SHOOTING OCCURRED, ACCORDING TO
POLICE, IN TWO ROOMS.
THEY MAY BE TWO CLASSROOMS.
WE CERTAINLY KNOW THAT THE
SHOOTER, WOLF, WAS FOUND DEAD IN
ONE OF THOSE CLASSROOMS AS WELL.
SO A LOT OF QUESTIONS, A LOT OF
HEARTACHE AND PEOPLE WALKING
AROUND THIS SMALL TOWN NOW IN
CONNECTICUT, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, IT'S SO HARD FOR
THEM TO BELIEVE AND TO
UNDERSTAND WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
BACK TO YOU.
>> THEY HAVEN'T SAID OFFICIALLY
THAT THE SHOOTER WOUND UP
KILLING HIMSELF, HAVE THEY?
>> Reporter: THEY HAVE NOT.
THEY HAVE NOT REVEALED THAT.
THEY HAVE NOT OFFICIALLY
RELEASED THE SHOOTER'S NAME
EITHER.
WE ALSO UNDERSTAND, REMEMBER,
THERE IS ANOTHER ADULT AT
ANOTHER LOCATION WHO WAS ALSO
FOUND DEAD AND WE BELIEVE THAT
THAT HAS SOME CONNECTION TO THE
SHOOTER IN THIS CASE, AND YET
SOMEONE ELSE WAS ALSO BEING
QUESTIONED.
SO THIS INVESTIGATION IS FAR
FROM OVER.
THERE IS A WARRANT BEING SERVED
AT THE PLACE WHERE THE SUSPECT
LIVED WITH SOMEONE ELSE, WHO WAS
ALSO INVOLVED IN THE SHOOTING.
AND SO A LOT OF QUESTIONS, OF
COURSE, AS WE ALL HAVE AT THIS
TIME TO FIND OUT HOW THIS
HAPPENED AND, WOLF, WHY THIS
HAPPENED.
>> MANY QUESTIONS THAT LAW
ENFORCEMENT WILL BE
INVESTIGATING.
SUSAN, STAND BY.
JOINING US ON THE PHONE RIGHT
NOW IS LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE, A
SPOKESMAN FOR THE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE.
HE'S IN NEWTOWN HIMSELF.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU HAVE THE
ANSWERS, LIEUTENANT, AND YOU
MUST BE OVERWHELMED RIGHT NOW.
BUT FIRST OF ALL, CAN YOU
IDENTIFY THE SHOOTER IN THIS
PARTICULAR CASE?
CAN YOU GIVE US THAT PERSON'S
NAME?
>> WOLF, WE DO HAVE A TENTATIVE
IDENTIFICATION, BUT FOR
INVESTIGATIVE REASONS WE'RE
HOLDING BACK THAT INFORMATION
FOR OUR OWN PURPOSES.
YOU ARE CORRECT IN SAYING THAT
THERE IS A SECONDARY SCENE IN
NEWTOWN AWAY FROM THE SCHOOL AT
A PRIVATE HOME WHERE THERE'S
ANOTHER DECEASED ADULT THAT MAY
BE RELATED TO THIS.
JUST FOR INVESTIGATORY REASONS,
WE'RE HOLDING BACK THAT IDENTITY
RIGHT AT THIS TIME.
>> CAN YOU TELL US IF THE
SHOOTER DID HAVE A CONNECTION,
THOUGH, TO THE SCHOOL?
THERE'S BEEN A LOT OF
SPECULATION THAT THE SHOOTER'S
MOTHER, FOR EXAMPLE, WAS A
TEACHER INSIDE ONE OF THOSE
CLASSROOMS.
>> WE NEED TO, AGAIN, BE
EXTREMELY CAUTIOUS IN RELEASING
THAT INFORMATION.
THAT WILL BE FORTHCOMING, I
WOULD SAY, WITHIN THE NEXT THREE
OR FOUR HOURS BUT AT THIS TIME
WE HAVEN'T DISCUSSED THAT AT
ALL.
>> IS THERE ANOTHER SUSPECT ON
THE LOOSE RIGHT NOW?
I WANT TO CLARIFY THAT BECAUSE
WE ARE GETTING CONFLICTING
INDICATIONS.
>> IN THE FASHION OF WHAT
OCCURRED AS FAR AS THIS SHOOTER
IS CONCERNED, I MEAN WE ARE
TALKING TO EVERYONE WHO POSSIBLY
HAD ANY CONNECTION WITH HIM
WHATSOEVER.
WE HAD TO OBTAIN SEARCH WARRANTS
TO SEARCH HIS RESIDENCE AND
PLACE OF EMPLOYMENT AND I
INTERVIEWED FRIENDS AND
RELATIVES AND WE ARE REALLY
ENSURING OR MAKING SURE THAT WE
LEAVE NO STONE UNTURNED INTO THE
BACKGROUND OF THIS INDIVIDUAL.
>> TO MAKE SURE THAT THE NUMBERS
THAT WE RECEIVED ARE PRECISE, 26
PEOPLE WERE SHOT AND 20 WERE
CHILDREN.
THE SHOOTER HIMSELF, DO WE
SUSPECT HE KILLED HIMSELF?
>> THAT WILL BE DWRMED BY THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER.
AS FAR AS WE KNOW THERE WAS NO
LAW ENFORCEMENT DISCHARGE OF
WEAPONRY.
IT'S IMPORTANT TO NOTE WHEN THE
CALL CAME IN, NEWTOWN POLICE
OFFICERS ALL RESPONDED
IMMEDIATELY AND UPON ARRIVAL
WENT IN WITH TACTICAL INJURY.
IMMEDIATELY ENTERED THE SCHOOL
AND BEGAN SEARCHING EVERY NOOK
AND CRANNY TO PERFORM A RESCUE
OF THE STUDENTS AND STAFF WE
POSSIBLY COULD.
WE DID ACCOMPLISH THAT TASK, BUT
ENCOUNTERED AS YOU SAID THE
DECEASED STUDENTS WHICH NUMBERED
18 IN THE SCHOOL AND TWO WERE
TRANSPORT AND PRONOUNCED DEAD
AND SIX ADULTS WERE PRONOUNCED
DEAD AT THE SCENE AND THEN THE
SECONDARY SENIOR WHICH WAS
ANOTHER ADULT.
>> CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT THIS
SCENE IF THERE WAS A CONNECTION
BETWEEN THE SHOOTER AND THE
PERSON WHO WAS DEAD?
>> IT'S ALL PRELIMINARY.
I AM DIRECTING 99% OF MY
ATTENTION TO THE SCHOOL.
YOU CAN UNDERSTAND THERE IS A
GREAT DEAL GOING ON TRYING TO
KEEP FAMILY AND FRIENDS AND
RELATIVES INFORMED AS FAR AS
WHAT WE KNOW.
WE CERTAINLY DISCOVERED THAT
SCENE IN CONCERT WITH THIS
INVESTIGATION AS I WAS SAYING.
WE DID A LOT OF WORK WE HAVE ALL
RELATED AREAS.
>> IN NEWTOWN ITSELF IN THIS
VICINITY IN THAT SMALLTOWN.
>> IT'S A SMALLTOWN.
IT'S NOT FAR AWAY.
I WOULD BE CONDIT WITH YOU.
IT WAS IN A RESIDENCE RIGHT HERE
IN THE TOWN.
THE SECONDARY SCENE WAS LOCATED
BY TROOPERS.
>> WE HAVE ONE CRIME SCENE AT
THE SCHOOL AND ANOTHER
INDIVIDUAL IS DEAD.
ARE THERE OTHERS THAT YOU ARE
SEARCHING OR LOOKING AT?
>> WE HAVE A GREAT DEAL OF
PERSONNEL HERE.
WE BROUGHT IN NOT JUST CRIME
TEAM, BUT ANOTHER.
WE ARE RESPONDING AND CHECK
EVERYTHING AND ANYTHING THAT
COULD POSSIBLY BE RELATED TO THE
TRAGEDY PARTICIPATING HERE.
JOHN KING IS HERE WITH US HERE
AT CNN AND HAS A QUESTION HE
WANTS TO ASK.
>> LIEUTENANT, I KNOW YOUR
OFFICERS ARE COLLECTING EVIDENCE
AT THE SCENE.
WHAT IS YOUR PRELIMINARY
ESTIMATE OF HOW MANY SHOTS WERE
FIRED IN THE SCHOOL?
>> THAT'S A TOUGH ONE.
I WOULDN'T EVEN VENTURE A GUESS
QUITE FRANKLY.
WE WILL HAVE TO DETERMINE THAT
WITH SEVERAL SYSTEMS OF CHECKS
AND BALANCES.
ONE CERTAINLY BEING A MEDICAL
EXAMINATION OF THE DECEASED AND
COLLECTING PHYSICAL EVIDENCE AND
SHELLS AND EXAMINING THE
WEAPONRY AND COLLECTING ANY
BULLETS THAT HAVE BEEN RANDOMLY
SHOT.
IT WILL BE A LONG PROCESS BEFORE
WE CAN GUESTIMATE THAT QUESTION.
>> I KNOW YOU ARE MAKING SURE
YOU CHECKED EVERY BOX, BUT IS IT
THE UNDERSTANDING THAT THE
SHOOTER CAME WITH A PRIMARY
TARGET ARMED FOR A MASS KILLING
AND CAME FOR A PRIMARY TARGET
AND SOURCES SAID THAT WAS HIS
MOTHER.
>> I CAN'T ANSWER THAT QUESTION
BECAUSE THE INFORMATION HAS NOT
BEEN PROVIDED AS OF YET.
>> WERE THERE EXPLOSIVES
PROVIDED IN ADDITION TO THE
WEAPONS?
>> NO.
THAT'S A GOOD QUESTION BECAUSE
ONCE THE SCENE WAS SECURE, WE
REALIZED THE TACTICAL TEAM WILL
CHECK THE SITES AND THE VEHICLES
AND ANYTHING TO DO WITH THE
SHOOTER TO ENSURE THAT THERE
WERE IN FACT NO EXPLOSIVES OR NO
OTHER ISSUES NEEDED TO ENGAGE.
>> DID THE SHOOTER IN ADDITION
COMING IN WITH THESE WEAPONS
ALSO HAVE -- WAS HE DRESSED IN
ARMOR AND DID HE HAVE PROTECTION
FOR HIMSELF?
>> I DON'T KNOW THE ANSWER TO
THAT.
>> HE WAS OBVIOUSLY FOUND
DEAD-ON THE SCENE AND NO OTHER
LAW ENFORCEMENT THAT CAME IN TO
KILL ANYONE.
PRESUMABLY THIS INDIVIDUAL WOUND
UP KILLING HIMSELF, BUT YOU
CAN'T CONFIRM THAT YET.
IS THAT RIGHT?
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
THAT'S A GOOD ASSESSMENT AS TO
WHAT WE KNOW SO FAR.
>> JOHN HAS ONE MORE QUESTION.
>> WE ARE TOLD THAT THE SECOND
SCENE THAT THE NEIGHBORS WERE
EVACUATEED FROM THEIR HOMES
AROUND THE HOME, WAS THAT AS A
PRECAUTION OR DO YOU HAVE AN
INDICATION OR CONCERN THAT THERE
HEAVY WEAPONS OR EXPLOSIVES?
>> IT'S A PROCEDURE OF WHAT WE
DO AND WE WANT TO BE CAUTIOUS
AND ERR ON THE SIDE OF CAUTION.
WE EVACUATED THE NEIGHBORS IN
THE EVENT THAT THERE WAS
ANYTHING THAT WAS HARMFUL AS WE
BEGIN TO EXAMINE THE SCENE.
>> WAS THIS PERSON A KNOWN
PERSON OF CONCERN TO LOCAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT OR WHEN YOU FOUND
OUT HIS IDENTIFICATION, YOU ARE
NOT RELEASING IT AND WHEN YOU
FOUND IT OUT, WAS IT A TOTAL
SURPRISE?
>> I AM NOT AWARE OF A SPECIFIC
HISTORY AND THAT'S SOMETHING
THAT THE DETECTIVES WILL LOOK AT
AS THEY CONTINUE THE EXAMINATION
OF THE ENTIRE CASE AND WE WILL
MAKE IT A POINT TO KNOW HIS
HISTORY.
EVERYTHING THAT WE WILL DO IN
THIS CASE.
>> WHEN ARE YOU RELEASE THE
NUMBERS, LIEUTENANT, ONE THING
IN ADDITION TO THE HUGE NUMBER,
26 PEOPLE KILLED AND 20 OF THEM
CHILDREN.
YOU POINTED OUT THAT ONE PERSON
WAS INJURED.
ONLY ONE INJURY.
WHAT DOES THAT SAY TO YOU THAT
26 PEOPLE WERE SHOT AND KILLED
AND ONLY ONE PERSON INJURED?
>> TO PUT IT BLUNTLY, THIS IS A
VERY, VERY TRAGIC SCENE FOR
EVERYBODY.
CERTAINLY OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN
FOR THE FAMILIES HERE.
THE FIRST RESPONDERS THAT HAD TO
GO TO THE SCHOOL AND SEE THE
CARNAGE AND THE DEATHS THIS TIME
OF YEAR, I CAN ALMOST HAVETIME.
THIS IS RIGHT UP THERE.
>> WHAT A HORRIFIC STORY.
LIEUTENANT VANCE, THANKS SO MUCH
FOR UPDATING THE VIEWERS HERE IN
THE UNITED STATES AND AROUND THE
WORLD.
THE STORY UNFORTUNATELY IS SO HO
HISK O RISK, BUT PEOPLE ALL OVER
THE WORLD ARE APPRECIATING
WHAT'S GOING ON AND WE ARE ONLY
BEGINNING TO GET THE BEGINNING
OF THIS INFORMATION.
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE IS WITH
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH, LIEUTENANT.
JOINING US NOW ON THE PHONE IS A
PARENT AS WELL.
TELL US WHERE YOU WERE AND WHAT
WAS GOING ON.
YOUR CONNECTION TO THE SCHOOL.
>> MY DAUGHTER IS A THIRD GRADER
AND SHE WAS THERE ACTUALLY IN
HER READING CLASS.
THEY HEARD BANGS AND THANK GOD
FOR MRS. SUMMERS.
HER READING TEACHER GRABBED MY
DAUGHTER AND BROUGHT HER INTO A
BATHROOM.
SHE LOCKED THE DOOR ALONG WITH
ANOTHER TEACHER.
IN A SHORT TIME, SOME POLICE
WERE ABLE TO GET THEM OUT OF
THERE AND ESCORT THEM THROUGH
THE HALL WAYS.
UNFORTUNATELY IT WAS A MESSY
SCENE FOR MY DAUGHTER.
>> I SPOKE WITH YOUR WIFE, LISA
AND SHE SAID YOUR DAUGHTER SEEMS
TO BE OKAY.
YOU ALSO HAVE A 10-YEAR-OLD SON.
HOW ARE THE KIDS DOING NOW?
>> I DON'T KNOW IF MY DAUGHTER
IS IN SHOCK OR NOT, BUT FROM
WHAT SHE TOLD ME SHE SAW, SHE IS
DOING INCREDIBLY WELL.
MY SON IS DOING GREAT TOO, BUT
THERE IS A LOT OF FEARS.
THE GAME IS CHANGED FROM THIS
POINT ON.
PER ARE WHAT DOES THAT MEAN WHEN
YOU SAY THE GAME IS CHANGED.
>> MY KIDS ARE ASKING WHEN IS IT
GOING TO HAPPEN AGAIN.
IT WAS ONLY A WEEK AGO WE WERE
TALKING ABOUT THIS TYPE OF
SITUATION AND I SAID THE CHANCES
OF IT HAPPENING ARE ONE IN A
ZILLION AT SANDY HOOK.
I WAS WRONG ABOUT THAT.
>> WE KNOW YOU KNEW THE
PRINCIPAL, DAWN HOCHSPRUNG WHO
WAS KILLED IN THE MASS MURDER
TODAY.
TELL US A LITTLE BIT ABOUT HER.
>> SHE WAS JUST SO NICE AND SHE
LOVED HER JOB.
ON A COUPLE OF OCCASIONS SHE
WENT OUT OF HER WAY JUST TO HELP
US WITH CERTAIN THINGS THAT WE
WERE WORKING ON WITH OUR
DAUGHTER.
THIS IS ALL SO SURREAL SO
FORGIVE ME IF I AM CLOUDY.
>> WE APPRECIATE IT AND CAN'T
IMAGINE WHAT YOU ARE GOING
THROUGH.
JOHN KING HAS A QUESTION.
>> SADLY IN ANY COMMUNITY WHEN
TRAGEDY LIKE THIS HAPPENS, THERE
NOTIFICATION SYSTEMS AND HOW
SPECIFIC WAS THAT INFORMATION
AND OBVIOUSLY THE OFFICIALS AT
THE SCHOOL WERE DEALING WITH A
TRAGEDY.
DO YOU THINK THAT PART WAS
HANDLED APPROPRIATELY?
>> I THINK THEY DID THE BEST
THEY COULD DO.
I DON'T KNOW HOW YOU PREPARE FOR
SOMETHING THIS CRAZY.
MY WIFE CALLED ME.
I WORK IN NEW YORK AND MY WIFE
TOLD ME THERE WAS A SHOOTING AND
I RUSHED HOME.
MY WIFE WAS ALREADY IN TOWN.
SO FAR THE NEWTOWN SCHOOL SYSTEM
HAS BEEN GREAT IN LEAVING
AUTOMATIC PHONE UPDATES WITH THE
PARENTS.
>> A SAD STORY.
QUICK QUESTION BEFORE I LET YOU
GO.
AT SOME POINT YOU WILL HAVE TO
MAKE A DECISION ABOUT LETTING
YOUR KIDS GO BACK TO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO?
>> THIS IS ALL SO NEW.
I HAVE BEEN TALKING TO MY KIDS
AND EXPLAINING THIS IS WHAT
HAPPENED.
YOU DO YOUR BEST TO COMMUNICATE
WITH THEM AND DO YOUR BEST TO --
IT'S FUNNY THAT A BOMB HITS AND
THERE IS A LOT OF SMOKE AND IT'S
STILL HERE.
I HAVEN'T HAD ENOUGH TIME TO
REALLY PLAN, BUT HOPEFULLY BY
THE TIME THEY GO BACK TO SCHOOL,
I WILL HAVE DONE A GOOD ENOUGH
JOB OF MAKING THEM FEEL AS
COMFORTABLE AS THEY CAN BE.
>> HOW IS YOUR WIFE DOING?
>> SHE IS HANGING IN THERE.
>> GIVE ALL OF THEM OUR LOVE AND
SYMPATHY AND SUPPORT.
WE WISH THEM ONLY THE BEST.
THIS IS A PARENT OF THE KIDS
FROM THAT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
THE KIDS GOT OUT OKAY, BUT
OBVIOUSLY 20 OTHER CHILDREN DID
NOT GET OUT OKAY.
18 OF THEM DIED ON THE SCENE AND
TWO OTHERS DIED AT THE HOSPITAL
AS A RESULT OF THE INJURIES.
>> I THINK A REMARKABLE
CONVERSATION DEALING WITH THE
UNTHINKABLE IN TRYING TO EXPLAIN
TO YOUNG CHILDREN IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE HOLIDAY SEASON THAT THE
UNTHINKABLE HAPPENED IN THEIR
SCHOOL AND FOR MANY OF THE
CHILDREN WHEN THEY GO BACK, MANY
OF THEIR FRIENDS WON'T BE THERE.
IT'S A TOUGH TASK FOR THE
PARENTS.
I WANTED TO WRAP UP THE
CONVERSATION AND UNDERSTANDABLY
YOU COVERED STORIES LIKE THIS IN
THE PAST.
THE POLICE ARE BEING CAREFUL
WHAT THEY SAY AND I WANTED TO
GIVE YOU MORE OF THE INFORMATION
I HAVE.
FEDERAL LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS BASED ON INFORMATION
FROM THEIR PEOPLE ON THE SCENE
AND THE STATE POLICE ON THE
SCENE DO BELIEVE THAT THE
SHOOTER SHOWED UP WITH THE
INTENT OF OBVIOUSLY ARMED FOR A
MASS KILLING, BUT THEY BELIEVE
HIS MOTHER, A TEACHER THERE WAS
THE PRIMARY TARGET AND MOST OF
THE DEVASTATION HAPPENED IN AND
AROUND HER CLASSROOM AT THE
SCHOOL.
THAT IS THE THEORY THEY ARE
OPERATING UNDER AS THEY COLLECT
THE EVIDENCE IN THE SCENE AND
THEY FOUND A FAMILY MEMBER SLAIN
AT THE SECOND SITE IN NEWTOWN
AND THEY ARE INTERVIEWING
FRIENDS AND ROOMMATES AS THEY
TRY TO PUT THIS TOGETHER.
THEIR BELIEF AT THIS POINT IS HE
ARRIVED AT THE SCHOOL AND WENT
DIRECTLY TOWARDS AND TO HER
CLASSROOM AND MOST OF THE
KILLING WAS DONE IN THAT AREA.
>> THE CHILDREN WERE KILLED
RIGHT THERE.
THEY FOUND THREE WEAPONS, IS
THAT RIGHT?
THESE ARE PRETTY SOPHISTICATED
WEAPONS THEY FOUND.
WHEN YOU HEAR THESE NUMBERS, 26
PEOPLE KILL AND 20 OF THEM
CHILDREN AND ONE INJURED.
IF YOU HAVE A SITUATION WHERE
PEOPLE ARE KILLED, THERE IS A
LOT OF OTHER PEOPLE.
LOOKS LIKE THIS PERSON WANTED TO
EXECUTE THIS PERSON.
I WAS TOLD THAT THE NUMBER OF
SPENT SHELLS WERE MIND-NUMBING.
WHEN THE GUNMAN OPENED FIRE, IT
WAS IN A CONCENTRATED AREA.
HE WAS IN THE IN THE HALLS.
IN AND AROUND HIS MOTHER'S
CLASSROOM, BUT THAT HE JUST KEPT
FIRING.
>> HE A LOT OF ROUNDS.
SOME OF THE EYEWITNESSS WERE
TELLING US THEY HEARD BOOM,
BOOM, BOOM, BOOM.
NEVER ENDING WHAT THEY HEARD
COMING FROM THE MIDDLE
CLASSROOMS.
>> THE NUMBER OF SHOTS FIRED
THAT I THINK IS THE REASON WHY
YOU DON'T HAVE FIVE, SIX, 15
PEOPLE TREATED AT THE HOSPITAL.
IT'S A LOW NUMBER.
BECAUSE OF THE DEVASTATION.
>> MARY SNOW IS ON THE SCENE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
YOU ARE OUTSIDE THE SHOOTER'S
MOTHER'S HOME WE RESPECT IN
NEWTOWN, IS THAT RIGHT?
>> Reporter: THAT'S RIGHT, WOLF.
YOU ARE TALKING TO LIEUTENANT
VANCE OF THE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE.
PRESUMABLY HE WAS TALKING ABOUT
THIS SCENE.
POLICE HAVE BEEN HERE FOR HOURS
NOW.
SEVERAL HOURS.
JUST ABOUT AN HOUR AGO, WE SAW A
S.W.A.T. TEAM LEAVING THE SCENE.
IT HAS BEEN BLOCKED OFF.
NOT ONLY TO US, BUT TO RESIDENTS
WHO CAN'T GO INTO THE HOMES.
WE DID ALSO SEE AN AMBULANCE
LEAVING THE SCENE ABOUT 3:15 AND
POLICE ARE BEING TIGHT-LIPPED
HERE ABOUT THE LOCATION WHERE
THEY ARE.
WE CAN YOU FROM RESIDENTS, ONE
WHO LIVED NEAR THE SUSPECT'S
MOTHER SAID THAT POLICE CAME IN
AT ABOUT 11:00 TO HER HOME AND
TOLD HERSHEY NEEDED TO GET OUT
RIGHT AWAY.
AT ONE POINT SHE WAS ESCORTED
BACK TO HER HOUSE AND TOLD SHE
HAD TO LEAVE AGAIN.
THERE IS NO TIME TABLE BEING
GIVEN TO THE RESIDENTS ABOUT
WHEN THEY CAN REENTER THEIR
HOMES.
MANY LAW ENFORCEMENT VEHICLES
ARE AT THIS SCENE AND IN TERMS
OF WHAT NEIGHBORS ARE SAYING,
THESE HOMES ARE FAR APART.
WE HAVEN'T FOUND MANY NEIGHBORS
WHO KNEW THE SUSPECT OR HIS
MOTHER, BUT WE REACHED ONE WOMAN
WHO JUST DESCRIBED THE SUSPECT
AT TROUBLED AND SAYING THE
PARENTS WERE DIVORCE AND DIDN'T
WANT TO GO FURTHER THAN THAT.
THIS COMMUNITY IS SO SHAKEN TO
THE CORE AND FILLING UP WITH
TEARS ANY TIME YOU APPROACH THEM
SAYING SO MANY YOUNG CHILDREN
ARE IN THE COMMUNITY.
>> THIS IS A SMALL COMMUNITY.
TO SET THE SCENE, ONLY ABOUT 80
MILES FROM NEW YORK CITY AND 40
MILES OR SO FROM HARTFORD.
UNDER 2,000 PEOPLE LIVE IN
NEWTOWN.
IT'S A SMALL COMMUNITY NOT FAR
FROM DANBURY, CONNECTICUT.
PEACEFUL AND WONDERFUL PLACE
WHERE WE HEARD FROM A LOST
INDIVIDUALS WITH FAMILIES WHO
MOVED THERE BECAUSE THE SCHOOL
SYSTEM IS CONSIDERED EXCELLENT
THERE AND DESPITE THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, KINDERGARTEN
TO FOURTH GREAT IS A WONDERFUL
SCHOOL ALTHOUGH THIS TRAGEDY
DEVASTATED SO MANY FOLKS.
>> Reporter: YEAH.
PEOPLE HAD SUCH HIGH PRAISE FOR
THE SCHOOL SYSTEM HERE AND IT
HAS BEEN DESCRIBED AS A SLEEPY
NEW ENGLAND TOWN.
IT'S LINED WITH BEAUTIFUL HOMES
ON A VERY QUIET ROAD HERE.
THE SHOCK IS SUCH AN UNDER
STATEMENT TO SAY THAT THAT'S
WHAT PEOPLE ARE SAYING.
THEY JUST HEAR IT OVER AND OVER
AGAIN THAT PEOPLE NEVER THOUGHT
SOMETHING LIKE THIS CAN HAPPEN.
>> THEY CAN'T BELIEVE IT AND IT
IS UNBELIEVABLE, BUT IT HAPPENED
AND IT'S REAL UNFORTUNATELY.
SO REAL.
MARY, STAND BY.
ADAM REECE IS IN HOBOKEN, NEW
JERSEY ACROSS THE RIVER FROM NEW
YORK CITY.
HE IS JOINING US.
WHAT'S THE CONNECTION, EXPLAIN
TO THE VIEWERS THE CONNECTION
BETWEEN WHAT HAPPENED IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT AND WHAT'S
GOING ON IN HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY
RIGHT NOW.
>> WOLF, WE BELIEVE THE SHOOTER
MAY HAVE LIVED HERE.
THIS MAY BE THE LOCATION WHERE
HE MAY HAVE SET OUT FROM THIS
MORNING TO HEAD UP TO NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
POLICE TELL US THEY HAVE IN
CUSTODY TWO PEOPLE WHO MAY HAVE
BEEN ROOMMATES OF HIS.
THEY ARE BEING QUESTIONED.
THEY DO NOT BELIEVE THEY WERE
INVOLVED IN THE SHOOTING.
FBI AND LOCAL POLICE AND A LOM
SQUAD HAVE BEEN HERE FOR MOST OF
THE AFTERNOON.
FBI AGENTS WENT BACK INTO THE
BUILDING.
IT'S A FIVE-STORY BUILDING AND
HAS TWO HALVES TO IT.
THREE BEDROOMS INSIDE.
IT'S A RENTAL AND I TALKED TO
SEVERAL RESIDENTS HERE WHO LIVE
IN THE BUILDING AND NEARBY.
NONE OF THEM KNOW THE SHOOTER,
ALLEGED SHOOTER OR HIS BROTHER
WHO MAY HAVE LIVED HERE.
THEY HAVE SEEN PICTURES IN NEWS
REPORTS.
THE PICTURES DO NOT LOOK
FAMILIAR TO THEM.
YOU MAY KNOW THAT HOBOKEN IS A
WATERFRONT COMMUNITY THAT LOOKS
ACROSS FROM NEW YORK CITY.
IT'S A GROWING COMMUNITY FOR
YOUNG PROFESSIONALS AND HIT HARD
BY HURRICANE SANDY.
WE WAIT AND THERE HAS BEEN NO
MOVEMENT OTHER THAN THE POLICE
HERE THAT YOU SEE IN THE PICTURE
STANDING GUARD.
FBI EDAGENTS ARE COMING BACK AN
FORTH.
>> THE WHOLE AREA IS CORDONED
OFF?
WE ARE LOOKING AT LIVE PICTURES
AND POLICE OFFICERS AND WE SEE
THE TAPE POSTED.
GIVE US A DESCRIPTION OF WHAT
YOU ARE SEEING.
>> AT LEAST TWO BLOCKS IN EAST
DIRECTION IS BLOCKED OFF.
A HUGE MEDIA PRESENCE WAITING TO
SEE WHAT DEVELOPED HERE AND
WHETHER OR NOT THIS IS IN FACT
THE HOME OF THE ALLEGED SHOOTER,
WHETHER OR NOT HIS BROTHER LIVED
HERE WITH HIM.
WHAT THE CONNECTION IS TO
NEWTOWN.
WHAT THE CONNECTION IS WITH HIS
MOTHER.
THERE IS A FACEBOOK PAGE THAT
INDICATES HIS HOME HERE, THAT HE
IS ORIGINALLY FROM NEWTOWN.
I CANNOT CONFIRM THAT'S HIM AND
HIS PAGE.
THAT'S ALL WE KNOW.
THE AREA IS CORDONED OFF AND AT
LEAST TWO BLOCKS IN EACH
DIRECTION.
>>> LOCAL POLICE THERE SAYING
ANYTHING PROVIDING THE NEWS
MEDIA WITH ANY INFORMATION?
>> THERE WAS A VERY SHORT
BRIEFING FROM THE LOCAL POLICE
CHIEF.
AS I INDICATED BEFORE, TWO
PEOPLE ARE IN CUSTODY.
THEY MAY BE THE SHOOTER'S
ROOMMATES, BUT THEY DON'T
BELIEVE THEY HAD INVOLVEMENT IN
THE SHOOTING.
>> WHEN WE SAY IN CUSTODY, IT
SOUNDS LIKE THEY HAD A ROLE.
MAYBE MORE PRECISELY, THEY ARE
JUST BEING QUESTIONED ABOUT WHAT
THEY KNOW OR MAY HAVE KNOWN
ABOUT THE ALLEGED SHOOTER.
>> RIGHT.
I DON'T WANT TO SUGGEST THEY HAD
ANY ROLE.
IT JUST MAY BE THEY ARE LOOKING
TO FIND OUT MORE BACKGROUND
INFORMATION ABOUT THE ALLEGED
SHOOTER.
>> I THINK THAT'S AN IMPORTANT
DISTINCTION THAT OR VIEWERS
APPRECIATE.
ANYTHING ELSE YOU WANT TO UPDATE
THE VIEWERS WITH?
>> ANXIOUSLY ANTICIPATING WHAT
MAY COME OUT OF THIS AND WHAT'S
INSIDE THE APARTMENT AND MAY
LEAD US TO UNDERSTAND WHY
SOMEONE MAY HAVE DONE THIS.
WHAT KIND OF READING MATERIAL HE
HAD AND WHAT IS ON HIS COMPUTER.
WE JUST DON'T KNOW.
>> THERE A LOT OF QUESTIONS THAT
WILL HAVE TO BE ANSWER AND IF
THERE IS A STATEMENT OR
INDICATION AS TO WHY THIS
INDIVIDUAL WENT TO THE SMALL
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT AND OPENED FIRE
KILLING A TEACHER OR PRINCIPAL
AND 20 CHILDREN IN GREATS
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADE.
WHAT A SHOCKING STORY.
WE WILL STAY IN CLOSE TOUCH WITH
YOU.
A YOUNG BOY AT THE SCHOOL WHERE
THE SHOOTING HAPPENED DESCRIBED
HOW HE AND OTHER CHILDREN
ESCAPED.
>> I WAS IN THE GYM AT THE TIME.
SO THE TEACHER AND WE HEARD A
LOST BANGS.
WE THOUGHT IT WAS THE CUSTODIAN
KNOCKING STUFF DOWN AND WE HEARD
SCREAMING.
WE WENT TO THE WALL AND SAT DOWN
AND THEN A POLICE CAME IN AND
SAID IS HE IN HERE AND RAN OUT.
OUR TEACHER AND SOMEONE YELLED
GET TO A SAFE PLACE.
WE WENT TO THE CLOSET IN THE
GYM.
WE SAT THERE FOR A LITTLE WHILE
AND THEN THE POLICE WERE
KNOCKING ON THE DOOR AND THEY
WERE LIKE WE ARE EVACUATING
PEOPLE.
WE RAN OUT AND THERE WERE POLICE
AT EVERY DOOR LEADING US DOWN
THIS WAY, DOWN THIS WAY, QUICK,
QUICK, COME ON.
WE RAN DOWN TO THE FIREHOUSE.
THERE WAS A MAN PINNED DOWN TO
THE GROUND WITH HANDCUFFS ON AND
WE THOUGHT THAT WAS THE VICTIM.
WE DIDN'T GET A GOOD GLANCE AT
HIM BECAUSE THERE WAS A CAR
BLOCKING IT.
PLUS WE WERE RUNNING REALLY
QUICK.
THEN WE GOT TO THE FIREHOUSE AND
WE SAT IN OUR CLASSES AND WE
WERE ALL REALLY HAPPY WE WERE
ALL ALIVE.
>> BY THE WAY, WHEN WE INTRUDE
THESE YOUNG KIDS, WE DO IT ONLY
WITH THEIR PARENTS'S PERMISSION.
THEIR PARENTS ARE THERE ON THE
SCENE.
WE DON'T TALK TO THE CHILDREN
UNLESS THE PARENTS SAY THEY WANT
THE CHILD TO SPEAK OUT AND THEY
ARE THERE TO WATCH THESE
INTERVIEWS.
WE ARE VERY SENSITIVE TO YOUNG
CHILDREN IN THESE KIND OF
TRAGEDIES.
OBVIOUSLY A LOT OF FAMILIES ARE
FEELING THE PAIN RIGHT NOW.
WE HEARD EARLIER FROM THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES.
LET'S BRING IN DR. DREW PINSKY,
THE HOST OF DR. DREW ON OUR
SISTER NETWORK, HLN.
WE HAVE BEEN TALKING ABOUT
WHAT'S GOING ON.
THESE KIND OF TRAGIC INCIDENTS
OFTEN CAN BE PREVENTED IF LOVED
ONES, FAMILY MEMBERS AND
NEIGHBORS AND FRIENDS PAY
ATTENTION TO WARNING SIGNS.
>> THAT'S RIGHT, WOLF.
PAYING ATTENTION IS THE BIG
LESSON FROM SO MUCH WE HAVE BEEN
HEARING IN THE NEWS.
DENIAL BY FAMILY MEMBERS AND
PARENTS IS THE ENEMY.
YOU CANNOT IMAGINE HOW MANY
SITUATIONS I HAVE BEEN IN WHERE
I GIVE FAMILY MEMBERS VERY
SPECIFIC DIRECTIONS TO PREVENT
DISASTERS AND THEY CHOOSE TO
STAY IN DENIAL AND COME TO TERMS
WITH THE FACT THAT THEIR LOVED
ONE IS NOT DOING WELL AND MAY
NOT BE TRUST WORTHY AND MAY BE
AGGRESSIVE OR VIOLENT.
AS I SIT AND LISTEN TO THE
STORY, I HAVE BEEN WATCHING THIS
WONDERFUL COVERAGE YOU HAVE BEEN
PROVIDING THAT HELPS US
UNDERSTAND WHAT HAPPENED AS THE
DAYS GO ON.
WE WILL TRY TO UNDERSTAND WHY IT
HAPPENED.
THE FEELINGS THAT RUSH OVER ME
AND RUN FROM SADNESS TO DISGUST
AND RAGE MYSELF.
DISGUST IS MOSTLY WHERE I FIND
MYSELF TODAY.
DISGUST THAT THESE LIVES SHOULD
HAVE BEEN EXTINGUISHED SO YOUNG,
WE CANNOT ALLOW THESE LIVES TO
HAVE BEEN LOST IN VAIN.
YOU DID A REMARKABLE INTERVIEW
WITH A FATHER OF A YOUNG CHILD
IN ONE OF THE ROOMS.
HE SAID THEY HAD JUST DISCUSSED
THE ISSUE AND I'M SURE HE WAS
TALKING ABOUT THE OREGON SHOOTER
AND REASSURING THIS IS CHILDREN
THIS COULD NEVER HAPPEN IN THEIR
COMMUNITY AND NOW HE IS
ADDRESSING THEM WITH THE
QUESTION THEY ARE ASKING HIM,
WHEN IS THIS GOING TO HAPPEN
AGAIN?
THAT IS THE QUESTION THAT EVERY
ONE OF OUR CHILDREN WILL ASK US
TONIGHT.
THEY WILL FEEL VULNERABLE AND
WHEN IS IT GOING TO HAPPEN TO US
AND HAPPEN AGAIN?
THESE STORIES ARE FLOODING THE
NEWS AND WE MUST, EACH OF US AS
A HOUSEHOLD LEAD OUR WAY OUT OF
THIS.
THIS REQUIRES LEADERSHIP.
OUR POLITICAL LEADERS ARE SORT
OF NOT GIVING US QUITE WHAT I
THINK WE NEED TODAY.
WE WILL BE OKAY.
THIS IS A RESILIENT COUNTRY AND
WE WILL GET THROUGH THIS.
WE ARE IN A NEW ZONE WHEN EVIL
PREVAILED.
WE ARE NOT GOING TO ALLOW THIS.
IT'S OKAY TO BE FIRM AND
EMPATHETIC WITH PEOPLE IF
SOMEONE IS MISBEHAVING.
BE FIRM AND TAKE ACTION.
WE WILL GET THROUGH THIS.
IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
THAT'S WHAT WE HAVE TO TELL OUR
KIDS.
>> WHAT MOTIVATES SOMEONE TO GO
OUT AND SHOOT AND KILL CHILDREN?
>> YOU ARE ASKING A QUESTION
THAT IT FILLS ME WITH DISGUST TO
HAVE TO ANSWER.
IT'S ONE THING TO EXPLAIN WHAT
HAPPENED IN OREGON.
PERHAPS THIS YOUNG MAN HAD A
BREAK OR WAS EXPOSED TO A
CHEMICAL OR SOMETHING THAT
CAUSED HIM TO THINK IN A
DISTORTED WAY.
THIS IS NOT JUST THAT.
THIS IS SOMEBODY WHO FELT
ENTITLE AND JUSTIFIED TO ACT
OUT.
THIS IS GRANDIOSITY AND FEELING
SPECIAL.
THIS IS FEELING LIKE HE IS MORE
IMPORTANT THAN ANY OF THESE
OTHER LIVES OR EXPOSED US TO
THIS VIOLENCE AND IS GOING TO
SHOW WHY HE IS SO IMPORTANT AND
FEEL VERY JUSTIFIED IN WHAT HE
IS DOING.
THIS IS A LONGER TERM KIND OF
DISTORTED THINKING THAN WHAT WE
SAW IN OREGON.
>> THEN THIS PERSON SUPPOSEDLY
WINDS UP KILLING HIMSELF.
IT SEEMS SO TOTALLY CRAZY.
>> RIGHT.
WHY WOULDN'T HE JUST KILL
HIMSELF?
WHY DOES HE HAVE TO TAKE THE
LIVES WITH HIM?
THAT IS THE GRANDIOSITY AND THE
DISTORTION AND THE ENTITLEMENT
AND AGGRESSION.
WHEN PEOPLE TALK ABOUT EVIL, I
SUSPECT THAT'S WHAT WE ARE
TALKING ABOUT HERE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED AND
THE DETAILS ABOUT THIS MAN'S
MENTAL HEALTH, BUT I SUSPECT
IT'S GOING TO BE CHRONIC SEVERE
TROUBLED BEHAVIOR THAT FOR
WHATEVER REASON WAS NOT PROPERLY
MANAGED.
>> BEFORE I LET YOU GO, CHEMICAL
IMBALANCES IN THE BRAIN,
SOMETIMES YOU HEAR PSYCHIATRISTS
AND PSYCHOLOGISTS TALKING ABOUT
SOMETHING THAT SNAPS AND CAUSES
PEOPLE TO DO THIS.
GIVE US YOUR SENSE.
>> THAT'S WHAT I WAS TALKING
ABOUT JUST DAYS AGO IN RELATION
TO OREGON.
THAT WAS MORE THAT KIND OF A
CIRCUMSTANCE.
THIS NO DOUBT THERE WAS STRESS.
ALL HUMAN BEHAVIOR IS BECAUSE OF
THIS INSTRUMENT UP HERE.
SOMETHING OBVIOUSLY DID CROSS A
THRESHOLD FOR HIM THAT CAUSED
HIM TO ACT OUT VIOLENTLY.
AGAIN THIS IS SOMETHING OF A
MORE CHRONIC, SEVERE, STRUCTURAL
WIRING NATURE IN THE BRAIN AND
REGIONS NOT FIRING OR NEVER
FIRING THAT WOULD ALLOW SOMEONE
TO BE EM PATHIC OR FEEL LIKE A
PART OF HUMANITY.
THERE PARTS OF THE BRAIN THAT
ALLOW US TO FEEL THAT WAY.
THOSE PARTS OF THE BRAIN IN
TERMS OF MISFIRING THE BRAIN, I
SUSPECT THOSE ARE THE AREAS WE
WILL SEE CHRONICALLY WERE NOT
OPERATING NORMALLY.
>> NOT NORMALLY AT ALL.
THANKS VERY MUCH FOR YOUR
PERSPECTIVE.
OUR PRODUCER HAS BEEN IN A
FIRESTORM HERE WHERE THE PANIC
RUSHED TO FIND THEIR CHILDREN
AND MANY OF THE PARENTS ARE
INSIDE RIGHT NOW INCLUDING
PARENTS WHO HAVE LOST THEIR
KIDS.
DESCRIBE THE INFORMATION YOU
HAVE SEEN AND HEARD.
>> WE HAD IMAGINE VEHICLES IN
AND AROUND THIS FIREHOUSE AND
THEY MAKE THEIR WAY TOWARDS THE
SCHOOL.
THIS IS THE STOPPING POINT WHERE
EMERGENCY VEHICLES STOP AT AND
HEAD TOWARDS THE SCHOOL.
WE HAVE SEEN ATF AND FBI.
MANY OF THEM CARRY ASSAULT
WEAPONS AND WEARING GEAR AND
LIKE YOU MENTIONED, THERE
FAMILIES STILL INSIDE THIS
FIREHOUSE.
I THINK IT'S A SHORT WHILE AGO
REALLY QUITE A MOVING SCENE.
THERE WERE THREE SETS IS OF
PRARNTS THAE CAN ONLY ASSUME
ARE PARENT COUPLES WALKING
OUT OF THE FIREHOUSE AND THEIR
EYES WERE BLOODSHOT AND LIPS
TREMBLING AND THE FIREMEN ES
CORING THEM OUT SEEMED AS
VISIBLY SHAKEN AS THEM.
THEY ARE NOT TALKING TO ANYONE,
BUT IT'S A SMALL SLICE OF WHAT'S
HAPPENING AND IT HAPPENED
THROUGHOUT THE DAY HERE.
SINCE I HAVE BEEN STANDING HERE,
YOU SEE THOSE PARENTS AND YOU
SEE THE INDIVIDUALS AND NURSES
AND YOU SEE SCHOOL CAFETERIA
WORKERS.
YOU SEE NUNS EVEN WALKING IN AND
AROUND AND SPEAKING WITH THOSE
EMERGENCY WORKERS AND SPEAKING
WITH PARENTS.
THERE FEW WORDS THAT YOU CAN PUT
TO SOMEONE.
ASK THEM ABOUT WHAT THEY ARE
FEELING.
I WAS THINKING ABOUT WHAT I
MIGHT SAY ABOUT ALL OF THIS.
IT'S ONE OF THE FEW INSTANCES
THAT LEAVES YOU WITHOUT WORDS TO
CAPTURE THE TREE MAGNITUDE OF
WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
I WALKED INTO TOWN EARLIER AND
SAT IN A RESTAURANT AND PEOPLE
ARE WATCHING THE NEWS.
THEY WILL PICK THEIR HEAD BACK
UP AND WATCH AGAIN.
OTHERS ARE AT THE MEDIA STAGING
AREA TO GET A SENSE OF WHAT IS
TRANSPIRING AND THE SENSE OF
WANTING TO BE WITH THE
COMMUNITY.
LIKE YOU MENTIONED, THIS IS A
SMALL SLEEPY TOWN IN NEW
ENGLAND.
THERE IS A CEMETERY THAT SITS
OVER THE OVERPASS THAT LOOKS ON
TO THAT FIREHOUSE AND DOWN THE
ROAD IS THE SCHOOL.
WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT WHAT
TRANSPIRED IN THAT SCHOOL, IT'S
LIKE DR. DREW SAID, IT LEAVES
WITH YOU A SENSE OF DISGUST.
>> TOTAL DISGUST.
IT'S GOING TO BE DARK THERE
PRETTY SOON, BUT THE FIREHOUSE
WHERE YOU ARE, THE PARENTS AND
LOVED ONES ARE BEING CONSOLED BY
GRIEF COUNSELLORS AND OTHERS.
CLERGY INSIDE AS WELL.
WE SPOKE TO A RABBI WHO IS
INSIDE CONSOLING THE FAMILY
MEMBERS.
>> WHAT YOU CAN DO TO CONSOLE
SOMEONE WHO JUST LOST A CHILD.
SOMEONE AT THAT AGE, I CAN'T
BEGIN TO IMAGINE.
THE WORD INCONSOLABLE APPLIES
HERE.
THIS IS SOMETHING THAT THE
COMMUNITY IS GOING TO BE DEALING
WITH AND REALING FOR FOR A LONG
TIME NOW.
YOU TALK TO RESIDENTS AND GET
THE SENSE THAT A LOT OF THESE
PEOPLE KNOW EACH OTHER.
A LOT OF PEOPLE MOVED TO THE
AREA FROM WHAT THEY TOLD BECAUSE
OF THE SCHOOL SYSTEM.
I TALKED TO A TREECHER WHO SAID
THAT.
TO HAVE SOMETHING LIKE THIS TAKE
PLACE IN ONE OF THE SCHOOLS AND
ONE OF THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS AT
THAT, IT JUST LEAVES YOU WITHOUT
WORDS.
>> DAVID, THANKS VERY MUCH FOR
THAT UPDATE.
ONE OF OUR PRODUCERS ON THE
SCENE.
WE HAVE MARY SNOW THERE AND
SUSAN CANDIOTTI.
WE HAVE OTHER REPORTERS AND
PRODUCERS WATCHING WHAT'S GOING
ON IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
ALSO WE SAW ADAM REECE ON THE
SCENE IN HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY, A
CONNECTION BETWEEN A RESIDENTIAL
AREA AND WHAT UNFOLDED AT THE
SMALL ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
I WANT YOU TO LISTEN IT A LOCAL
NURSE WHO RAN TO THE SCENE SOON
AFTER THE SHOOTING AND DESCRIBED
WHAT SHE SAW.
>> I SEE YOU HAVE BEEN CRYING.
>> YES.
>> IS IT BECAUSE OF WHAT YOU
SAW?
>> NO, THEY WOULDN'T LET US IN
THE BUILDING.
ALL I CAN SAY IS ONE OF THE COPS
SAID IT WAS THE WORST THING HE
HAD SEEN IN HIS ENTIRE CAREER.
IT WAS WHEN THEY TOLD ALL THESE
PARENT WHO IS WERE WAITING FOR
THEIR PARENTS TO COME OUT, THEY
THOUGHT THEY WERE STILL ALIVE.
THERE IS 20 PARENTS THAT WERE
JUST TOLD THEIR CHILDREN ARE
DEAD.
IT WAS AWFUL.
>> AWFUL INDEED.
ASHLEIGH BANFIELD IS NOW ON THE
SCENE FOR US IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT AS WELL.
I KNOW YOU GOT THERE A LITTLE
WHILE AGO, BUT GIVE OUR VIEWERS
A SENSE OF WHAT YOU ARE SEEING
AND HEARING.
>> I'M IN THE SAME PLACE THAT
THE CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR DAN
MALLOY UPDATED US ALL.
YOU CAN SEE FROM THE COLLECTION
OF MICROPHONES THIS IS A
CONCENTRATED MEDIA CENTER.
THERE DOZENS OF REPORTERS HERE
AND ARRIVING EVERY MOMENT.
I HATE TO BRING THIS UP, BUT IT
GIVES ME THE SENSE OF COLUMBINE
AND HOW MASSIVE THE SCOPE OF
THIS STORY HAS BECOME.
ONE OF THE UPDATES WE GOT,
DEVASTATING DETAIL ON THIS.
THAT IS THE INVESTIGATION THAT
IS ABOUT TO ENSUE.
WOLF, THE BODIES OF THOSE
CHILDREN ARE STILL IN THE
SCHOOL.
18 CHILDREN DIED IN THE SCHOOL
AND WERE DEAD ON THE SCENE.
TWO MORE TAKEN TO THE HOSPITAL
AND DIED THERE.
THE SIX ADULTS ALSO WHO DIED AT
THE SCHOOL, THEIR BODIES ARE
STILL THERE.
THE POLICE WHO UPDATED US TOLD
US THAT THE SCOPE OF THE
INVESTIGATION, THE AMOUNT OF
WORK THEY HAVE TO DO TO PIECE
THIS ALL TOGETHER IS GOING TO
TAKE A VERY LONG TIME.
YOU CAN IMAGINE HOW THE PARENTS
ARE DEALING WITH THE FACT THAT
THEY CAN'T EVEN GET THE
INFORMATION OR AT LEAST KNOW
THAT THEIR CHILD IS BEING
BROUGHT OUT OF THAT SCHOOL.
IT IS JUST OVERWHELMING IN THIS
TINY COMMUNITY OF 27,000 PEOPLE.
IN THE STICKS.
WHEN YOU DRIVE HERE, YOU ARE
WINDING ROADS AND HILLS AND THE
HOMES ARE FAR APART AND YET THE
COMMUNITY IS QUITE CLOSE
TOGETHER.
A COUPLE OF OTHER THINGS THAT
SHED LIGHT ON THE DETAIL ON HOW
THE SHOOTING TOOK PLACE, THE
POLICE TOLD US THAT THE
SHOOTINGS WERE CONCENTRATED AND
THEY WERE IN AN AREA OF THE
SCHOOL, PARTICULARLY TWO ROOMS.
THERE WASN'T RUNNING THROUGH THE
HALLS AS THEY DESCRIBED IT.
NO SHOOTER RUNNING THROUGH THE
HALLS AND SHOOTING.
IT MIGHT GIVE SOME DESCRIPTION
AS TO WHY WE THINK THERE WAS A
CONCENTRATION OF ONE ENTIRE
DLASZ IS UNACCOUNTED FOR THAT
THE SHOOTING HAPPENED IN THOSE
TWO ROOMS.
THERE WAS ANOTHER CRIME SCENE
NOW IN THIS TINY TOWN OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
POLICE ARE INVESTIGATING ANOTHER
IN A HOME.
WE CAN TELL YOU THAT THERE WERE
MANY COUCH TERMS BEING USED.
PEOPLE ARE BEING VERY CAREFUL IN
HOW THEY REPORT THIS, BUT THEY
SAID THE SHOOTER IN THE SCHOOL
LIVED WITH ONE OF THE VICTIMS.
WE ALSO KNOW THAT HIS MOTHER WAS
A KINDERGARTEN TEACHER AND SHOT
DEAD IN THE SCHOOL.
WHETHER THAT IS THE HOME WHERE
THEY ARE INVESTIGATING AS WELL
IS UNCLEAR.
HIS FATHER LIVING IN THE TOWN AS
WELL AND A BROTHER TOO.
THERE IS A LOT OF DETAIL WE NEED
TO PIECE TOGETHER.
ANOTHER DETAIL THAT CAME FROM
THE MOUTH OF A CHILD WITH THE
SWEETEST VOICE WHO IS BEING
INTRUDE EARLIER THIS AFTERNOON.
THIS CHILD TOLD A STORY OF HOW
THE TEACHERS TRIED TO PROTECT
THEM FROM THE INFORMATION AS
THEY WERE GETTING THEM OUT OF
THE SCHOOL, SAYING THERE WAS AN
ANIMAL IN THE SCHOOL AND THAT'S
WHY THEY NEEDED TO LOCK THE
DOORS TO PROTECT THEM FROM THE
NOISE THEY COULD HEAR WHICH WAS
A WILD ANIMAL THAT GOT INTO THE
SCHOOL.
TO HEAR THAT TINY VOICE TELLING
THAT, IT WAS PRETTY REMARKABLE.
>> I KNOW THIS IS A DIFFICULT
STORY FOR ALL OF US TO COVER.
I KNOW YOU HAVE CHILDREN.
>> I HAVE TWO SMALL CHILDREN IN
A CONNECTICUT SCHOOL ABOUT 30
MINUTES AWAY FROM HERE AS WELL.
WHEN THE NEWS BROKE IT WAS TOUGH
TO SORT OUT WHERE IT HAPPENED.
WHICH ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IT WAS.
AS THE DETAILS ROLL IN,
EVERYBODY HAS BEEN IMMENSELY
AFFECTED AND APOLOGIZE, BUT IT
IS REMARKABLE TO SEE THIS MANY
SEASONED REPORTERS WHO I HAVE
BEEN IN THE FIELD WITH FOR 20
YEARS ALL HAVING THE SAME
REACTION TO WHAT'S TRANSPIRED.
>> YOU CHOKED UP AND THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
IS CHOKING UP AND WIPING AWAY
TEARS AS WELL.
YOUR GIRLS, HOW ARE THEY?
YOUR KIDS.
>> MY KIDS ARE FINE.
WHAT'S INTERESTING IS EVEN
THOUGH THEY ARE ABOUT I HALF
HOUR AWAY FROM HERE, WHEN I
CALLED THE SCHOOL TO FIND OUT IS
EVERYTHING OKAY AND ARE WE UNDER
LOCKDOWN AND WHAT'S THE PROTOCOL
AND ARE YOU SENDING THE KIDS
HOME?
IT AFFECTED THEM DEEPLY.
DID PERIMETER CHECKS AND
MADE SURE THAT ALL THE LOCKED
DOORS WERE LOCKED.
THEY DID SOMETHING I DIDN'T KNOW
ABOUT.
THEY WENT INTO AN INFORMATION
PROTECTIVE MODE AND SAID NO ONE
IS ALLOWED TO DISCUSSIONS THE
DETAILS WITHIN THE SCHOOL LS.
IN THE ONLY 30 MINUTES AWAY, BUT
THEY WOULD HAVE STAFF AND
SECURITY OUTSIDE THAT SCHOOL
STO HANDLE THE PTIAL FOR
CHILDREN TO HEAR ABOUT IT.
THEY CLEARLY WANT THE KIDS TO
HEAR ABOUT IT FROM THEIR
PARENTS.
THEY ARE ALL GOING TO HEAR ABOUT
IT AND ASK QUESTIONS AND MAKE
SURE THEY ARE SENSITIVE TO THE
SURROUNDING CHILDREN AS THEY CAN
BE.
IT IS A REALLY OVERWHELMING
FEELING TO LIVE HERE AND TO BE
HERE AS A REPORTER.
>> IT'S A POWERFUL,OWERL
IMAGE THAT YOU ARE PRESENTING
AND JUST THINK ABOUT IT.
SATURDAY AND SUNDAY, KIDS DON'T
HAVE TO GO TO SCHOOL, BUT MONDAY
MORNING, KIDS IN YOUR
NEIGHBORHOOD AND NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT AND ALL OVER THE
UNITED STATES, THEY ARE GOING TO
BE GOING BACK TO SCHOOL THE WEEK
BEFORE CHRISTMAS AND WHAT AN
AWFUL TIME TO HAVE TO ENDURE
THIS PAIN.
>> I TELL YOU WHAT, WOLF.
THE SCHOOL IS BEYOND THOSE
TREES.
I DON'T KNOW IF IT'S LIGHT
ENOUGH TO SEE.
WE ARE LOCATED IN THE STAGING
AREA WHERE THE POLICE WANTED TO
MAKE SURE THE HUNDREDS OF MEDIA
THEY WOULD SEND HERE WOULD BE
ABLE TO BE SAFELY PARK AND OUT
OF THE WAY OF THE RESIDENTS.
BEYOND THIS PLAYING FIELD AND
OVER THOSE TREES IS WHERE THE
SCHOOL IS LOCATED.
BECAUSE ONE OF THE DESCRIPTIONS
THAT CAME IN FROM SOMEONE WHO
WAS IN A MEETING WITH SEVEN
GROWN UP WHEN IS THIS HAPPENED,
THERE WERE ROUGHLY 100 ROUNDS
THAT THIS PARENT COULD HEAR.
A WOMAN TELLING HER STORY.
THE INVESTIGATION ALONE, ONCE
THE TINY BODIES ARE REMOVED AND
THE ADULTS ARE REMOVED.
THE INVESTIGATION OF THE
TRAJECTORY AND WHERE THE BULLETS
LANDED OR ANGLE THE BULLETS CAME
FROM, THERE WAS SO MUCH THAT
WILL NEED TO BE KNOWN.
I DOUBT ANYONE WILL BE COMING TO
THIS SCHOOL FOR A LONG TIME.
>> POLICE ARE GOING TO BE
GETTING THEIR INVESTIGATION.
PLEASE STAND BY.
I WILL COME BACK TO YOU AND I
KNOW YOU ARE COLLECTING MORE
INFORMATION HERE IN WASHINGTON.
THERE IS A VIGIL OUTSIDE THE
WHITE HOUSE AND A LOT OF PEOPLE
ARE GATHERING RIGHT NOW.
THE PRESIDENT ORDERED ALL FLAGS
FLOWN AT HALF-STAFF UNTIL
DECEMBER 18th.
YOU CAN SEE THE PICTURES COMING
IN FROM THE WHITE HOUSE.
THESE ARE PEOPLE WHO WANT GUN
CONTROL AND THEY ARE HOLDING A
VIGIL OUTSIDE THE WHITE HOUSE
RIGHT NOW INSIDE THE WHITE
HOUSE.
A LITTLE WHILE AGO, PRESIDENT
OBAMA WENT INTO THE BRIEFING
ROOM TO ADDRESS THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE AND BECAME VERY
EMOTIONAL.
>> THIS AFTERNOON I SPOKE WITH
GOVERNOR MALLOY AND FBI DIRECTOR
MULLEN.
I OFFERED GOVERNOR MALLOY MY
CONDOLENCES ON BEHALF OF THE
NATION AND MADE IT CLEAR HE WILL
HAVE EVERY SINGLE RESOURCE THAT
HE NEEDS TO INVESTIGATE THIS
HEINOUS CRIME, CARE FOR THE
VICTIMS, COUPLE THEIR FAMILIES.
WE HAVE ENDURED TOO MANY OF
THESE TRAGEDIES IN THE PAST FEW
YEARS AND EACH TIME I LEARN THE
NEWS, I REACT NOT AS A
PRESIDENT, BZ ANYBODY ELSE
WOULD, AS A PARENT.
THAT WAS ESPECIALLY TRUE TODAY.
I KNOW THERE IS NOT A PARENT IN
AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL KIDS BETWEEN THE AGES
OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS AND MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES TO HELPING
OUR CHILDREN FULFILL THEIR
DREAMS.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN TODAY.
FOR THE PARENTS AND
GRANDPARENTS, SISTERS AND
BROTHERS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN AND FOR THE FAMILIES OF
THE ADULTS WHO WERE LOST.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN FOR THE
PARENTS OF THE SURVIVORS AS
WELL.
FOR AS BLESSED AS THEY ARE TO
HAVE THEIR CHILDREN HOME
TONIGHT, THEY KNOW THEIR
CHILDREN'S INNOCENCE HAS BEEN
TORN AWAY FROM THEM TOO EARLY
AND THERE NO WORDS THAT WILL
EASE THEIR PAIN.
AS A COUNTRY WE HAVE BEEN
THROUGH THIS TOO MANY TIMES.
WHETHER IT'S AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN OR A SHOPPING
MALL IN OREGON OR TEMPLE IN
WISCONSIN OR A MOVIE THEATER IN
AURORA OR A STREET CORNER IN
CHICAGO.
THESE NEIGHBORHOODS ARE OUR
NEIGHBORHOODS AND THESE CHILDREN
ARE OUR CHILDREN.
WE ARE GOING TO HAVE TO COMING
TO AND TAKE MEANINGFUL ACTION TO
PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS
REGARDLESS OF THE POLITICS.
THIS EVENING MICHELLE AND I WILL
DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT IN
AMERICA WILL DO WHICH IS HUG OUR
CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER AND
TELL THEM WE LOVE THEM AND WE
WILL REMIND EACH OTHER HOW
DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
THERE FAMILIES WHO CANNOT DO
THAT TONIGHT.
THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT NOW.
OUR DAYS TO COME, THAT COMMUNITY
NEEDS US TO BE AT OUR BEST AS
AMERICANS AND I WILL DO
EVERYTHING IN MY POWER AS
PRESIDENT TO HELP.
BECAUSE WHILE NOTHING CAN FILL
THE SPACE OF A LOST CHILD OR
LOVED ONE,ALL OF US CAN EXTEND
A HAND TO THOSE IN NEED TO
REMINDHEM THAT WE'RE THERE FOR
THEM AND WE ARE PRAYING FOR THEM
AND THAT THE LOVE THEY FELT FOR
THOSE THEY LOST ENDURES NOT JUST
IN THEIR MEMORIES, BUT IN OURS.
MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF THE
VICTIMS AND IN THE WORDS OF
SCRIPTURE, HEAL THE
BROKENHEARTED AND BIND UP THEIR
WOUNDS.
>> THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES OBVIOUSLY VERY, VERY
EMOTIONAL LIKE SO MANY MILLIONS
AND MILLIONS OF PEOPLE ALL OVER
THE COUNTRY RIGHT NOW.
WE WILL TAKE A QUICK BREAK AND
RESUME THE SPECIAL COVERAGE
RIGHT AFTER THIS.
[ "THE ODD COUPLE" THEME
PLAYING ]
HUMANS.
EVEN WHEN WE CROSS OUR "T"s
AND DOT OUR "I"s,
WE STILL RUN INTO PROBLEMS --
MAINLY OTHER HUMANS.
AT LIBERTY MUTUAL INSURANCE,
WE UNDERSTAND.
THAT'S WHY OUR
AUTO POLICIES COME WITH
ACCIDENT FORGIVENESS
IF YOU QUALIFY,
WHERE YOUR RATES WON'T GO UP
DUE TO YOUR FIRST ACCIDENT,
AND NEW CAR REPLACEMENT,
WHERE IF YOU TOTAL
YOUR NEW CAR,
WE GIVE YOU THE MONEY
FOR A NEW ONE.
CALL...
TO TALK TO
AN INSURANCE EXPERT ABOUT
EVERYTHING ELSE
THAT COMES STANDARD
WITH OUR BASE AUTO POLICY.
[ TIRES SQUEAL ]
AND IF YOU GET INTO AN ACCIDENT
AND USE ONE OF OUR
CERTIFIED REPAIR SHOPS,
YOUR REPAIRS ARE
GUARANTEED FOR LIFE.
CALL...
TO SWITCH,
AND YOU COULD SAVE HUNDREDS.
LIBERTY MUTUAL INSURANCE --
RESPONSIBILITY.
WHAT'S YOUR POLICY?
.
>>> WE ARE CONTINUING THE
BREAKING TRAGIC NEWS OUST
CONNECTICUT.
26 PEOPLE WERE KILLED AND 20 OF
THEM CHILDREN WHEN A GUNMAN
OPENED FIRE IN A SMALL
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
CHILDREN KILLED WERE AGES 5
THROUGH 10.
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADE.
HOW DO FAMILIES AND CHILDREN
COPE WHEN A TRAGEDY HAPPENS LIKE
THE ONE THAT UNFOLDED TODAY IN
CONNECTICUT?
LISA SYLVESTER IS HERE AND
TAKING A CLOSER LOOK AT THIS
STORY.
IT HIT SO POWERFULLY.
YOU HAVE KIDS AND THE PERIOD HAS
KIDS.
WE HEARD ASHLEIGH BANFIELD
REACT.
>> I HAVE A KINDERGARTENER AND
YOU SAY YOU WAIVE GOODBYE TO
YOUR CHILD AND THEY HAVE THEIR
BACKPACK AND YOU ASSUME YOU WILL
SEE THEM LATER.
I DON'T THINK THERE IS A PARENT
OUT THERE WHO HAS SEEN THIS
STORY AND NOT IMPACTED BY WHAT
HAPPENED TODAY.
FOR PARENTS IT IS HARD TO
COMPREHEND OR SAY THE WORDS 20
CHILDREN KILLED.
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT A CLASS OF
VERY YOUNG CHILDREN.
HOW DO YOU MAKE SENSE OF IT ALL?
IT'S HARD AS AN ADULT AND A
PARENT, BUT IT'S TOUGHER IF YOU
ARE A CHILD.
IF THERE IS AN IMAGE THAT SUMS
UP THIS STORY, IT IS THIS.
ANY PARENT OUT THERE CAN RELATE.
PSYCHIATRIST CHARLES RAISIN IS
WITH THE UNIVERSITY OF ARIZONA'S
COLLEGE OF MEDICINE.
>> HOW DO YOU WRAP YOUR MIND
AROUND SOMETHING LIKE THIS?
WITH A GOOD DEAL OF HEART BREAK
WITH THE UNDERSTANDING THAT WILL
IT TAKE A WHILE AND THERE WILL
BE PEOPLE THAT WERE CLOSELY
IMPACTED BY THIS WHO WILL NEVER
WRAP THEIR MINDS AROUND THIS.
THE HUMAN MINDS ARE NOT
INFINITE.
THIS IS APPEARING TO BE PROBABLY
THE WORST SCHOOL CATASTROPHY IN
HISTORY.
THERE WILL BE A HUGE FALLOUT FOR
THIS THAT WILL ALSO IMPACT THE
PEOPLE'S EMOTIONAL WELL BEING
AND WE NEED TO GEAR OURSELVES UP
FOR THE FALLOUT.
THIS IS A HORRIBLE THING.
>> THE NEWS IS TRAUMATIC FOR
PARENTS AND CHILDREN.
THIS HAPPENED AT A SCHOOL WHERE
KIDS ARE SUPPOSED TO FEEL SAFE.
>> HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN IT TO
CHILDREN?
IT DEPENDS ON THE AGE OF THE
CHILD, BUT SIMPLE FORTHRIGHT
EXPLANATIONS ARE THE BEST.
ONE OF THE THINGS I TELL
CHILDREN IS THERE SOME BAD
PEOPLE IN THE WORLD AND
SOMETIMES BAD PEOPLE DO TERRIBLE
THINGS.
A TERRIBLE THING HAPPENED AND
THERE HAVE BEEN CHILDREN KILLED.
THIS IS TERRIBLE, BUT YOU ARE
SAFE AND YOU NECESSARY A
SITUATION NOW WHERE YOU ARE NOT
GOING TO BE HARMED.
>>.
>> THE AMERICAN ACADEMY OF
PEDIATRICS SAID TAKE INTO
ACCOUNT THE AGE OF THE CHILD AND
DO NOT OFFER DETAILS THAT MAY AH
LARM THEM.
ASK THEM WHAT THEY KNOW AND
ANSWER QUESTIONS.
PARENTS CAN SHARE FEELINGS IN
THE WAY THEY ARE COPING AND FIND
WAYS TO HELP OTHERS.
>> CHILDREN ARE RESILIENT AND
WHAT MATTERS NOW IS HOW WE HELP
THEM UNDERSTAND WHAT'S HAPPENED
AND EVEN I THINK MORE
IMPORTANTLY --
>> HERE'S THE POLICE CHIEF.
LET'S LISTEN IN FOR THE LATEST.
>> WE ARE LIMITED AS TO SOME OF
THE DETAILS WE CAN GIVE OUT TO
YOU FOR OBVIOUS REASONS.
FIRST LET ME STATE THAT I HAVE
TOLD YOU THE NUMBER OF DECEASED
IN THE BUILDING AND THE HOSPITAL
AND THE SECONDARY CRIME SCENE.
IT'S OUR POLICY THAT WE HAVE TO
ESTABLISH POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATION OF THOSE VICTIMS.
IT'S A TIME CONSUMING PROCESS
AND SOMETHING THAT WILL TAKE A
GREAT DEAL OF TIME.
THEY WORKED CLOSELY TO EXPEDITE
THAT AND GET IT DONE AS
EFFICIENTLY AS POSSIBLE.
AS I TOLD YOU, THE FAMILIES HAVE
BEEN ASSIGNED A TROOPER OR
OFFICER AS A LINE OF
COMMUNICATION.
THAT WAS DONE TO ENSURE THE
FAMILIES THAT THEY HAVE CONSTANT
COMMUNICATION WITH THE
INVESTIGATION AND THEY WON'T
HAVE ON SIT AND WATCH TELEVISION
NEWS OR ANYTHING.
THEY WILL BE THE FIRST TO KNOW
ANY OF THE PROGRESS THAT IS MADE
AS THE INVESTIGATION CONTINUES
ON.
AS I STATED EARLIER, THE ASSETS
UTILIZED INITIALLY WERE WHEN THE
CALL CAME IN, NEWTOWN POLICE
DEPARTMENT RESPOND AND CALLED
FOR HOSPITAL.
THEY SENT OUT OFFICERS AND THE
STATE POLICE SENT OFF DUTY AND
ON DUTY TROOPERS TO RESPOND TO
GAIN ACCESS TO THE BUILDING AND
BEGIN THAT SEARCH PROCESS THAT I
ALLUDED TO BEFORE.
WE HAD THE SAY THE POLICE TEAM
AND CANINE TEAMS OUT HERE.
WE HAD TROOPER IN THE AIR AND
TAKE SOME OF YOUR HELICOPTERS
AWAY, QUITE FRANKLY, BUT EVERY
POSSIBLE ASSET CAME OUT TO THE
SCENE THE MINUTE THIS ALARM CAME
IN OR THIS CALL CAME IN.
IT WAS CERTAINLY TO DO
EVERYTHING WE COULD TO PROTECT
AND PROPERTY.
THE COMMUNITY HAS BEEN
OUTSTANDING IN SUPPORTING THE
EFFORT.
YOU HAVE TAKEN OVER THEIR PARK
AND THEY ARE SHOWING UP AND
OFFERING CONDOLENCES AND DOING
EVERYTHING THEY POSSIBLE LOW CAN
TO SUPPORT THE VICTIMS.
THE VICTIMS'S FAMILIES OF THIS
HORRIFIC TRAGEDY.
THE FBI CRISIS MANAGEMENT TEAM
OFFERED TO RESPOND HERE TOMORROW
TO ASSIST A CRISIS MANAGEMENT
AND NOT ONLY WITH THE FAMILIES
AND THE FAMILY MEMBERS, BUT WITH
ALL THE FIRST RESPONDERS AND THE
POLICE AND FIRE AND EMS.
ALL WORKING AT WHAT I DESCRIBED
AS A HORRIFIC AND DIFFICULT
SCENE.
CERTAINLY A LOCAL MENTAL HEALTH
CRISIS INTERVENTION TEAM HAD
BEEN ON SCENE AND HAVE BEEN HERE
ALL OF TODAY WORKING AND
ASSISTING AND HELPING.
I WANTED TO MAKE IT CLEAR THAT
THERE WERE 18 CHILDREN
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCENE AND
TWO CHILDREN TRANSPORTED TO AREA
HOSPITALS AND PRONOUNCED DEAD AT
THE HOSPITAL.
SIX ADULTS PRONOUNCED DEAD AT
THE SCENE AND OBVIOUSLY THE
SHOOTER WAS ALSO PRONOUNCED DEAD
AT THE SCENE.
I DON'T HAVE MUCH DETAIL ABOUT
THE SECONDARY SCENE, BUT THERE
IS A RELATED SCENE WE DISCOVERED
AS WE WERE CONTINUING THE
CRIMINAL INVESTIGATION AND
SPECIFICALLY INVESTIGATING THE
SHOOTER.
YOU PROBABLY SAW AND SOMEONE
ASKED ME ABOUT THE BOMB SKAD AND
YES, WE BROUGHT ALL OUR ASSETS
IN IN CASE THEY WERE NEEDED AND
WE WENT OUT TO SEARCH OR EXECUTE
SEARCH WARRANTS OR EXAMINE OTHER
SCENES, WE TOOK THEM WITH US TO
ENSURE THEY WERE RIGHT THERE TO
REACT IF IT WAS NECESSARY.
THAT'S ABOUT ALL I HAVE AS FAR
AS THE DETAILS ARE CONCERNED.
I WANT TO GIVE YOU ONE MORE
BRIEFING AND TRY IT GET BACK UP
HERE FOR MORE BRIEFING.
I WILL TAKE A COUPLE OF BRIEF
QUESTIONS, BUT I MUST TELL YOU
THERE CERTAIN THINGS WE CANNOT
DISCUSS.
>> DO WE HAVE ANYONE IN THE
HOSPITAL NOW THAT SURVIVED THIS?
>> NO, SIR.
ONE PERSON WAS INJURED THAT
SUFFERED AN INJURY AND DID
SURVIVE, YES.
>> CAN YOU CONFIRM THE BODY OF
THE MALE?
>> I CAN'T CONFIRM.
I KNOW ABOUT THE SECONDARY SCENE
AND I DIDN'T HAVE TIME TO GET
INTO DETAIL.
I WILL DO THAT FOR 6:00.
>> WHAT'S THE SHOOTER'S
IDENTITY?
>> I WILL NOT CONFIRM THAT.
WE HAVE A TENTATIVE
IDENTIFICATION AND WORKING WITH
THAT.
WE WILL NOT CONFIRM THE IDENTITY
AND PUT THAT OUT THERE.
WE WILL AT AN APPROPRIATE TIME.
IT'S NOT APPROPRIATE TO DO THAT
RIGHT NOW.
>> WHAT HAPPENED WITH THE
INVESTIGATION IN HOBOKEN?
>> IT'S PART AND PARCEL OF WHAT
WE DO.
WE WILL LEAVE NO STONE UNTURNED
AS WE ELECTRIC AT EVERY FACET OF
THE INVESTIGATION WHETHER IT'S
THE SHOOTER OR THE VICTIMS.
WE WILL LOOK AT EVERYTHING.
WE CERTAINLY WILL GO IN AND OUT
OF STATE AND WORK WITH FELLOW
LAW ENFORCEMENT INCLUDING
FEDERAL AGENCY FIST WE NEED TO
TO ANSWER EVERY QUESTION TO
EXACTLY WHAT TRANSPIRED HERE AND
IT WILL BE A CROSS THAT WILL GET
IT DONE.
>> RIGHT NOW, ONE SHOOTER.
YES, SIR.
>> IT WAS K-4.
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRID.
THAT'S THE SCHOOL.
THEY WERE ALL STUDENTS OF THAT
SCHOOL.
I DON'T KNOW THE GRADE THEY WERE
IN.
I DON'T KNOW THAT.
IT WAS ONE SECTION AND TWO
CLASSROOMS.
I COULDN'T TELL YOU.
I DIDN'T FIND THAT OUT.
YOUR QUESTION?
THAT'S PART OF THE PROCESS.
THAT'S WHY IT TOOK US A LONG
TIME TO GET HERE.
ANY STUDENTS UNACCOUNTED FOR, WE
HAD TO ENSURE THAT WE ACCOUNTED
FOR EVERY STUDENT AND THAT
INCLUDES MAYBE SOMEONE THAT WAS
ABSENT FOR THE DAY BECAUSE OF
ILLNESS AND DIDN'T COME TO
SCHOOL.
THAT WAS PART OF THE PROCESS WE
HAD TO GO THROUGH AND NOW WE
HAVE THE IDENTIFICATION PROCESS
WHICH IS EVEN MORE DIFFICULT.
IT'S SOMETIME BEFORE WE ARE ABLE
TO GIVE YOU THAT INFORMATION.
IT PROBABLY WON'T BE AVAILABLE
UNTIL SOMETIME TOMORROW.
DID WE IDENTIFY THE WEAPONS?
YES, WE HAVE.
>> HOW MANY?
>> WE WILL NOT DISCUSS THAT AT
THIS TIME.
>> YOU REACHING THE PARENTS?
>> WE WOULD NOT COME UP HERE
UNTIL WE HAVE BEEN IN CONTACT
WITH THE PARENTS AND
COMMUNICATING WITH THEM SINCE
THEY ARRIVED HERE AT THE SCENE.
THEY HAVE BEEN FULLY INFORM AND
THAT'S WHY IT TOOK SO LONG TO
COME UP HERE.
>> HOW WERE THE FIRST RESPONDERS
DEALING WITH THIS.
NO ONE CAN EXPECT TO WALK INTO A
SCHOOL AND SEE THOSE MASS
CASUALTIE
CASUALTIES.
>> THAT'S A GOOD QUESTION.
EVERYONE BELIEVES THAT IT'S
SOMETHING THAT FIRST RESPONDERS
DO AND LAW ENFORCEMENT DOES, BUT
WE PROVIDED COUNSELING FOR THE
FIRST RESPONDERS BECAUSE THIS
WAS A VERY TRAGIC HORRIFIC SCENE
THEY ENCOUNTERED.
IT'S NOT SOMETHING WE WANT TO
SEE.
IT'S NOT SOMETHING WE SEE EVERY
DAY.
THAT'S ONE THING WE HAD DONE AND
THE COLONEL MADE THAT PERFECTLY
CLEAR THAT THOSE PEOPLE ARE TO
BE SPOKEN TO AND RECEIVE CRISIS
COUNSELING AS REQUIRED.
>> YOU HAVE TO BE THE FACE OF
WHAT'S HAPPENING AND --
[INAUDIBLE].
>> THE LIEUTENANT CAN TELL YOU.
>> A PERSON -- [INAUDIBLE].
>> CAN YOU SAY YOUR NAME,
PLEASE?
>> LIEUTENANT GEORGE CINCO.
SINKO.
>> YOU CAN TELL US ALSO THE ONES
YOU HAVE.
>> THIS IS MOST DEFINITELY THE
WORST THING WE HAD EXPERIENCED
HERE IN TOWN.
TRAGIC.
RIGHT NOW WE ARE CONCERNED ABOUT
THE FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS.
OUR OFFICERS ARE PROFESSIONAL
AND WE WILL DEAL WITH THIS AS
WELL.
>> YOU CAN DESCRIBE THE SCENE
WITH THE PARENTS AND THE PLACE
WHERE PEOPLE ARE GETTING
TOGETHER?
>> THE LOCAL HOSPITAL OFFERED
CRISIS INTERVENTION AND WILL BE
AVAILABLE AT REED INTERMEDIATE
SCHOOL AND THEY ARE AVAILABLE
RIGHT NOW IF NEED BE AND WILL BE
THERE ALL WEEKEND.
>> IS THERE A PLACE WHERE
PARENTS ARE GATHERING AND CAN
YOU DESCRIBE THAT?
>> THE PARENTS HAVE GATHERED AT
THE LOCAL FIREHOUSE WHICH IS
ADJACENT TO THE SCHOOL AND WE
HAVE DONE OUR BEST TO COMFORT
THEM AND TRY TO REASSURE THEM
THAT WE HAVE DONE EVERYTHING WE
CAN.
AS MENTIONED, IT'S A DIFFICULT
PROCESS TO CONFIRM THE STATUS OF
AN ENTIRE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE NEED TO BE RIGHT WHEN WE DO
THAT.
.
>> WE HAVE TO THINK ABOUT THE
FAMILIES RIGHT NOW AND DO
EVERYTHING WE CAN FOR THEM.
>> WAS ONE OF THE TEACHERS --
[INAUDIBLE].
>> WE CAN'T CONFIRM THAT RIGHT
NOW.
THE INVESTIGATION IS ONGOING.
>>> THE PARENTS STILL THERE?
>> THERE PARENTS THERE, YES.
I DON'T HAVE A NUMBER FOR YOU.
>> WHEN DID YOU REALIZE THE
MAGNITUDE?
HOW LONG DID IT TAKE?
>> MINUTES AFTER THE OFFICERS
WERE THERE THEY REALIZED WHAT A
HORRIFIC SCENE WE HAD.
[INAUDIBLE]
>> I DON'T HAVE THE EXACT
TIMELINE ON THAT.
OFFICERS RESPONDED IMMEDIATELY
AND AS SOON AS THEY REALIZED
WHAT THEY HAD, WE ASKED FOR THE
RESOURC
RESOURCES.
ALL RIGHT?
THANK YOU.
>> WE JUST FINISHED.
WE WILL COME BACK AROUND 6:00
AND GET BACK WITH ONE MORE
BRIEFING AND A SCHEDULED
BRIEFING PROBABLY TOMORROW.
SOME OF YOU FOLKS LOOK TIRE AND
WANT SOME REST.
WE WILL SEE IF WE CAN GIVE YOU A
SCHEDULE FOR TOMORROW.
OKAY?
>> THERE WE HAVE THE LATEST
COMING FROM THE STATE POLICE
FROM LOCAL LAW ENFORCEMENT IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE WANT TO WELCOME BACK THE
VIEWERS IN THE UNITED STATES AND
AROUND THE WORLD.
THIS IS BREAKING NEWS.
UNIMAGINABLE HORROR GRIPS THE
NATION IN ONE OF THE DEADLIEST
SCHOOL SHOOTINGS IN U.S.
HISTORY.
A TRAGEDY SO WRENCHING IT
REDUCED THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES TO TEARS.
RIGHT NOW 27 PEOPLE ARE
CONFIRMED DEAD IN CONNECTICUT'S
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
MASSACRE.
20 CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS AND
THE ALLEGED SHOOTER.
ALL OF THIS HAPPENING WITHIN A
MATTER OF A FEW HOURS.
WATCH THIS.
THE SIGHTS AND SOUNDS OF THIS
TRAGEDY AS IT PLAYED OUT.
>> WHEN I WAS GETTING IN MY CAR,
I HEARD SIRENS GOING OFF
CONTINUOUSLY.
CAR AFTER CAR AFTER CAR.
SOME OF THEM WERE FLYING PAST MY
HOUSE AND COMING AROUND AGAIN
AND GOING TO THE SCHOOL.
THIS HOUSE IS THREE HOUSES AWAY
FROM THE SCHOOL.
>> WHEN WE FIRST ARRIVED, THERE
WAS NOT A LOT OF SECURITY TO
GUARD.
THERE WERE THREE CHILDREN THAT
CAME OUT.
ONE OF THEM HAD A VERY BLEED
FACE.
>> HE IMMEDIATELY JUMPED IN THE
CAR AND HEADED DOWN HERE.
IT'S TROUBLING.
IT WAS MAYHEM IN THE ROOM WITH
THE KIDS AND THE TEACHERS AND
TRYING TO IDENTIFY YOUR KID AND
MAKING SURE THEY ARE AND FINDING
OUT WHAT THE SITUATION WAS AND
MAKING SURE EVERYONE WAS SAFE.
IT STARTED WITH THE NEIGHBORS
AND THE REST OF THEIR FRIENDS.
>> WHAT DID YOUR DAUGHTER SAY TO
YOU?
>> THEY WERE IMMEDIATELY CRYING.
PETRIFIED OF WHAT HAPPENED AND
WHAT DID IT MEAN AND THEY ARE
OLDER THAN THE OTHER KIDS IN THE
SCHOOL SO UNDERSTANDING WHAT
HAPPENED, MY SON WAS IN THE GYM
WHEN IT HAPPENED.
I THINK THEY HEARD THE GUNSHOTS.
>> WE SAW POLICE OFFICERS AND
HEARD THEM ON THE ROOF AND IN
OUR BUILDING.
>> DID YOU HEAR GUNSHOTS OR
ANYTHING LIKE THAT?
>> THE POLICE OFFICERS WERE KIND
OF.
THERE WERE POLICE OFFICERS OUT
THE DOOR TRYING TO FIND THE GUY.
>> IT WAS SHOCKING.
I GOT THE CALL AT WORK THIS
MORNING.
I CAN'T BELIEVE A SMALL DOWN
LIKE THIS WOULD HAVE ANYTHING
LIKE THIS HAPPEN.
TO BE IN AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
IT'S UNHEARD OF.
>> IT DOESN'T EVEN SEEM REAL.
IT DOES NOT SEEM LIKE IT'S EVEN
POSSIBLE.
YOU READ IT IN THE NEWSPAPER OR
SEE IT IN THE NEWS AND YOU ARE
LIKE MY GOD, THAT POOR FAMILY.
THEN YOU HAVE SOMETHING HAPPEN
SO CLOSE TO HOME.
I THINK I'M STILL IN SHOCK.
>> I CAN TELL YOU THAT OUR
HEARTS AND PRAYERS GO OUT TO THE
VICTIMS OF THIS TERRIBLE
INCIDENT.
VERY TRAGIC.
OUR POLICE ARE CURRENTLY WORKING
CLOSELY WITH THE NEWTOWN POLICE
DEPARTMENT AND MUTUAL AIDE THAT
ALLOWS US TO PROVIDE ASSETS THEY
MAY NOT HAVE ALONG WITH THE
STATE POLICE THAT HAVE TAKEN THE
LEAD IN THIS INVESTIGATION.
>> IT WAS TERRIFYING AND I'M
STILL IN SHOCK ABOUT IT ALL.
>> WAS EVERYBODY CRYING AND
SCARE AND WANT THEIR PARENTS TO
COME GET THEM?
>> YEAH, THEY WERE AND SOME
PEOPLE WERE EVEN LIKE KIND OF
FELT LIKE THEY GOT A STOMACH
ACHE.
>> THEY WOULDN'T LET US IN THE
BUILDING.
ONE OF THE COPS SAID IT WAS THE
WORST THING HE HAD SEEN IN HIS
ENTIRE CAREER.
WHEN THEY TOLD THE PARENTS AND
THEY WERE WAITING FOR THE
CHILDREN TO COME OUT AND THEY
THOUGHT THEY WERE STILL ALIVE.
THERE IS 20 PARENTS THAT WERE
TOLD THAT THEIR CHILDREN ARE
DEAD.
IT WAS AWFUL.
>> AWFUL.
YOU CAN'T IMAGINE HOW AWFUL IT
MUST BE FOR THE PARENTS AND
LOVED ONES AND THE FAMILY
MEMBERS IN THE SMALL TOWN OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THIS IS A SMALL ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
GRADES KINDERGARTEN THROUGH
FOURTH GREAT.
5 THROUGH 10-YEAR-OLDS.
20 OF THEM GUNNED DOWN BY A
KILLER TODAY.
SIX ADULTS KILLED AS WELL.
MARY SNOW IS JOINING US NOW FROM
OUTSIDE THE SUSPECT'S MOTHER'S
HOME WE BELIEVE.
IS THAT CORRECT?
>> THAT IS CORRECT.
WE JUST LEFT THE LOCATION AND WE
HAD BEEN THERE SEVERAL HOURS
THROUGHOUT THE AFTERNOON.
THE INVESTIGATION STRETCHED TO
THAT HOME AND IT'S BEING TREAT
SAID AS A CRIME SCENE.
WE FOUND S.W.A.T. TEAMS AND WE
CAN TELL YOU THAT THE RESIDENTS
NEAR THAT HOME WERE TOLD TO
EVACUATE EARLIER TODAY.
WE TALKED TO ONE NEIGHBOR WHO
SAID SHE WAS TOLD AROUND 11:00
THIS MORNING BY POLICE TO GET
OUT RIGHT AWAY.
SHE IS OUT OF HER HOME ABLE TO
GET INTO HER HOUSE.
AS FAR AS WHAT WE SAW, THEY ARE
BEING TIGHT-LIPPED ABOUT THAT
LOCATION WHERE THE INVESTIGATION
HAD CONTINUED.
I CAN TELL YOU THAT IN ADDITION
S.W.A.T. TEAMS, WE DID SEE AN
AMBULANCE AT ONE POINT WHILE WE
WERE THERE LEAVING SHORTLY AFTER
3:00 THIS AFTERNOON.
NEIGHBORS WERE NUMB REALLY.
A NUMBER OF THEM COULDN'T EVEN
TALK TO US.
THEY ARE SO FILLED WITH EMOTION.
ONE NEIGHBOR DID TALK TO US.
SHE KNEW THE FAMILY OF THE
SUSPECT AND DESCRIBED HIM AS
TROUBLE AND DIDN'T ELABORATE
FURTHER THAN THAT.
IT IS BEING PUT TOGETHER WITH
THE SUSPECT'S FAMILY.
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT OUTSIDE
THE SUSPECT'S MOTHER'S HOME.
WE ARE GETTING MORE INFORMATION.
SIZE
SUSAN CANNED LOTIY IS GETTING
MORE INFORMATION.
WALK US THROUGH WHAT WE KNOW AT
THIS POINT.
ALL OF THIS IS SUBJECT TO
CHANGE.
THE INFORMATION IS STILL COMING
IN.
WALK US THROUGH WHAT WE KNOW AND
HOW IT WENT DOWN.
>> YOU ARE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT TO
CAUTION ABOUT THIS.
WHAT WE DO KNOW.
I COVERED AN AWFUL LOT OF SCHOOL
SHOOTINGS OVER THE YEARS AND THE
EARLY INFORMATION ALWAYS SEEMS
TO CHANGE.
THIS IS WHAT WE KNOW ABOUT THE
TIMELINE OF THE SHOOTINGS AS
REPORTED BY LAW ENFORCEMENT AND
WITNESSES AND THE LAY OUT OF THE
SCHOOL AS BEST WE CAN PIECE IT
TOGETHER.
REMEMBER THIS IS JUST A VERY
ROUGH APPROXIMATATION.
ABOUT 9:30 THIS MORNING, CLASS
HAS BEEN UNDER WAY FOR ABOUT A
HALF HOUR.
MORE THAN 600 STUDENTS, THE
SCHOOL PRINCIPAL AND VICE
PRINCIPAL AND THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST AND SEVERAL OTHER
ADULTS WERE HAVING A MEETING UP
HERE IN THIS PART OF THE SCHOOL.
THEY GATHERED NEAR THE OFFICE
AREA AT THAT TIME.
AROUND 9:40 ACCORDING TO WHAT A
LOT OF EYEWITNESSS HAVE TO SAY
IS WHEN IT APPEARED THE GUNMAN
ENTERS THE BUILDING.
WE DON'T REALLY KNOW HOW.
WE KNOW THAT LATER TODAY POLICE
WERE LOOKING AT A CAR OUT HERE
PARKED BY A FIRE LANE.
BASED ON WHAT EYEWITNESSS SAID,
THERE WAS A GOOD REASON TO THINK
HE CAME THROUGH THE FRONT DOOR
INTO THIS AREA.
WE DON'T HAVE A GUARANTEE, BUT
IT SOUNDS LIKE THAT.
RIGHT AWAY PEOPLE THROUGHOUT
THIS ENTIRE BUILDING STARTED
HEARING SHOTS.
SOME CASES THEY SAID IT SOUNDED
LIKE BANGS OR SOMEONE HAMMERING.
PEOPLE STARTED SAYING THEY COULD
HEAR SOMETHING.
BY 9:41 OR SO, CALLS WERE COMING
INTO 911.
THE PRINCIPAL AND THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST ACCORDING TO
WITNESSES WERE IN A MEETING IN
THIS PART OF THE BUILDING CAME
OUT OF THAT MEETING AND THEY GO
TOWARDS THE GUNFIRE OUT HERE IN
A HALL WAY.
HERE OR HERE.
THEY GO OUT THERE AND THE PEOPLE
IN THE ROOM SAY THEY HEAR MANY,
MANY MORE SHOTS AND A LOT OF
SHOUTING AND THE VICE PRINCIPAL
COMES BACK IN WOUNDED.
THE OTHER TWO DO NOT.
AUTHORITIES SAY THE SHOOTING
APPEARS TO HAVE HAPPENED IN A
RELATIVELY SHORT PERIOD OF TIME
AND THE GUNMAN DOES NOT ROAM
AROUND AND STAYS RIGHT IN THE
AREA HERE.
YOU HEARD IT OVER AND OVER AGAIN
FROM THE OFFICER THERE.
TWO ROOMS IS WHERE IT ALL
HAPPENED.
AROUND 9:45 OR SO, TEACHERS IN
THE REST OF THE BUILDING FROM
ALL WE CAN HEAR FROM STUDENTS
AND OTHER PEOPLE WHO HAVE SPOKEN
ABOUT IT ARE DOING ALL THEY CAN
TO PROTECT THEIR STUDENTS.
THEY DON'T KNOW WHAT IS GOING
ON.
THEY WERE NEAR THE GYM AND TOLD
TO HIDE IN CLOSETS AND THAT SORT
OF THING.
OTHERS IT APPEARS THE SCHOOL
WENT INTO LOCKDOWN, BUT THEY
STARTED LEADING STUDENTS AWAY
FROM THE SCHOOL.
I'M NOT SURE OF THE TIMELINE,
BUT WE KNOW THAT BY THE TIME THE
OFFICERS SHOWED UP ON THE SCENE,
YOU STARTED HAVING A SITUATION
WHERE STUDENTS WERE BEING LED
AWAY BY OFFICERS AND TEACHERS
AND EVERYBODY WHO COULD TRY TO
GET THEM OUT TO SAFETY.
SOMETIME LATER, WE WILL PUT IT
AT 9:50, BUT WE DON'T REALLY
KNOW BECAUSE IT'S MURKY AND WE
WILL GET CLARITY OVERTIME.
IT'S NOT CLEAR HOW OR WHEN THE
GUNMAN DIES.
WE KNOW OFFICERS SAID NO OFFICER
FIRED A GUN THAT LEADS YOU TO
BELIEVE HE SHOT HIMSELF.
WE DON'T REALLY KNOW.
AS OFFICERS ARRIVE ON THE SCENE,
THEY IMMEDIATELY TAKE CONTROL OF
THE ENTIRE BUILDING.
THEY SPREAD OUT AND SECURING
ROOMS AND MAKING SURE THEY KNOW
THAT IF THEY HAVE THE FUNMAN,
IT'S 1 AND THERE IS NOT SOMEONE
ELSE.
THEY ARE LOOKING EVERYWHERE FOR
THE POCKETS OF CHILDREN.
THEY KNOW THERE KIDS HIDDEN IN
THE BUILDING.
IN ALL THE SCHOOL SHOOTINGS I
HAVE SEEN, THIS IS A COMMON
OCCURRENCE AND THE SHOOTING
BEGINS WITH MANY TEACHERS
HELPING THEM AND GO INTO HIDING.
THAT IS A VERY, VERY DANGEROUS
SITUATION WHEN THE OFFICERS GO
INTO THE BUILDING.
I HAD OFFICERS SAY YOU HAVE
PEOPLE POPPING OUT BEHIND YOU
WHO WERE IN CLOSETS AND ROOMS
AND THE OFFICERS HAVE TO BE
PROFESSIONAL AND CALM TO GET
THROUGH THAT AND CONTROL THE
SITUATION.
THAT'S PRECISELY WHAT THEY DID
AND AT THAT POINT YOU HAVE A
SITUATION WHERE YOU WERE ABLE TO
SEE THE OF OFFICERS SECURING THE
PROPERTY ALL-AROUND AND TRYING
TO MAKE SURE THEY CAN SEE THAT
THE GUNMAN WAS THERE AND LEADING
THE KIDS OUT AS WE HEARD PASSED
ACTUAL VICTIMS OF THE SHOOTING.
AGAIN, ALL OF THE TIMELINE IS
VERY, VERY TENTATIVE RIGHT NOW
AND WE ARE GOING TO GET A LOT
MORE, BUT THE BOTTOM LINE IS IT
LOOKS LIKE IT TOOK MAYBE 20 OR
30 MINUTES AT MOST FROM
BEGINNING TO END FROM THE TIME
TO SHOOTER WALKED IN TO THE TIME
THE POLICE OFFICERS ESSENTIALLY
HAD EVERYTHING SECURED AND WERE
GOING THROUGH TO MAKE SURE THEY
HAD EVERYTHING TAKEN CARE OF AND
THE KIDS CLEARED OUT.
THAT'S A LONG PROCESS THAT IS
GOING ON ALL DAY.
>> DURING THE FEW MINUTES, 26
PEOPLE WERE MURDERED.
SIX ADULTS AND 20 YOUNG
CHILDREN.
WHAT A HORRIFIC STORY.
THANKS VERY MUCH.
LET'S GO TO THE SCENE RIGHT NOW
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
SUSAN CANN
SUSAN CANNED LOTIY IS THERE.
>> I LEARNED THAT THE MOTHER OF
THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER WHO HAS
BEEN IDENTIFIED AS NANCY LANZA
WAS FOUND DEAD.
I HAVE BEEN TOLD THAT NO
PHYSICAL BODY WAS FOUND IN
ANOTHER HOME IN HOBOKEN, NEW
JERSEY.
THERE HAVE BEEN OTHER PUBLISHED
REPORTS ABOUT THAT.
TWO SOURCES DO TELL US THAT
SOMEONE WAS TAKEN AWAY FOR
QUESTIONING FROM THAT HOUSE IN
HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY AND THAT
CONCERN IS BELIEVED TO BE THE
SUSPECT'S BROTHER IN THIS CASE.
IN OTHER WORDS, THE BROTHER OF
THE SUSPECTED DEAD SHOOTER IN
THIS SCHOOL SHOOTING.
THE SHOOTER HAS BEEN DESCRIBED
TO ME AS HAVING WORN OR DRESSED
IN BLACK BATTLE FATIGUES AND A
MILITARY VEST WHEN HE CAME INTO
THE SCHOOL AND BEGAN FIRING
AWAY.
I KNOW ACCORDING TO SOURCES THAT
AT LEAST THREE WEAPONS HAVE BEEN
RECOVERED.
ONE DESCRIBED AS A MODEL 223
BUSH WACKER, A MILITARY STYLE
SEMI AUTOMATIC GUN.
SOME OF THE AMMO IS USED IN
AFGHANISTAN BY OUR SOLDIERS
THERE.
THAT TWO OTHER GUNS WERE ALSO
FOUND THAT ARE DESCRIBED AS HAND
GUNS.
ONE A GLOCK.
>> THE BOTTOM LINE IS THAT THE
MOTHER WHO WAS A TEACHER AT THAT
SCHOOL WAS FOUND DEAD AT HER
HOME WHERE MARY SNOW IS OUTSIDE
THAT HOME BECAUSE ORIGINALLY WE
THOUGHT THE MOTHER WAS ENGINE
THE CLASSROOM WHERE THE GUNMAN
OPENED FIRE.
>> EARLIER WE HAD INFORMATION
THAT SHE WAS FOUND IN THE
CLASSROOM, HOWEVER NOW I'M TOLD
THAT IN FACT HER BODY WAS FOUND
AT THE SUSPECT'S RESIDENCE HERE
IN THIS PARTICULAR AREA.
WE DON'T KNOW WHETHER SHE ALSO
LIVED THERE.
WE DON'T KNOW.
WE ALSO DON'T KNOW THE TIMELINE.
WHEN WAS SHE KILLED?
WAS SHE KILLED BEFORE THE
SHOOTING BEGAN AT THE SCHOOL?
THESE ARE THE THINGS THAT
AUTHORITIES ARE STILL TRYING TO
PIECE TOGETHER.
ALSO WE HAVE CONFLICTING
INFORMATION ABOUT THE SHOOTER'S
NAME.
WE HAVE HAD THE NAME FOR QUITE
SOMETIME AND THERE IS SOME
QUESTION AS TO WHETHER THE
SHOOTER IS DESCRIBED -- WHICH
BROTHER'S NAME IS WHICH.
WE HAVE THEIR AGES AND THE
NAMES, BUT WE ARE TRYING TO SORT
THAT OUT.
OFFICIALS HAVE YET TO OFFICIALLY
RELEASE THAT YET.
>> THIS KIND OF STORY, IT'S NOT
UNUSUAL THAT CONFLICTING
INFORMATION COMES IN AND WE
CONSTANTLY UPDATE AND REVISE AS
WE GET MORE DETAILS.
INITIAL REPORTS PROVE TO BE
INACCURATE.
WE ARE GETTING CONFLICTED
INFORMATION.
WE WILL PIECE IT TOGETHER IN
ABOUT 20 OR 25 MINUTES.
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
WILL HAVE ANOTHER BRIEFING AND
MAYBE WE WILL GET MORE DETAILED
INFORMATION AT THAT TIME.
SUSAN IS ON THE SCENE AND WE
HAVE ALL OF OUR REPORTERS AND
PRODUCERS THERE IN NEWTOWN AND
ALSO THE INVESTIGATION
CONTINUING IN HOBOKEN, NEW
JERSEY.
HEART BREAKING NEWS COVERAGE
RESUMES AFTER THIS.
-
>>> I SAW SOME OF THE BULLETS
GOING PAST THE HALL THAT I WAS
RIGHT NEXT TO AND THEN A TEACHER
PULLED ME INTO HER CLASSROOM.
>> YOU HEARD SOUNDS?
>> YES.
>> WHAT DID IT SOUND LIKE?
>> IT SOUNDED LIKE SOMEONE WAS
KICKING A DOOR.
>> IT DIDN'T SOUND LIKE GUN
SHOUTS?
>> NO, IT DIDN'T.
>> THAT WAS A YOUNG BOY FROM THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
HIS PARENTS ARE THERE WHEN OUR
AFFILIATES ARE THERE AND WHEN WE
SPEAK TO THEM, WE ONLY DO IT
WITH THEIR PARENTS'S PERMISSION.
WE WANT TO UPDATE THEM ON THAT.
SO MANY OF THEM CAME CLOSE TO
BEING KILLED BOY A KILLER WHO
WENT INTO THAT SCHOOL.
WE WENT THROUGH POINT BY POINT
WHAT HAPPENED.
THE TEACHERS WERE OVER THERE AT
THE SCHOOL CLASS AND ATTENDANCE
SHEETS CAME OUT.
IT WAS CLOSE FOR SO MANY YOUNG
KIDS AS WE WATCHED AND MORE
DETAILS.
OUR LOCAL AFFILIATE WATCHED WHAT
WAS GOING ON AND CAUGHT UP WITH
A MOTHER WHO WAS THANKFUL TO THE
TEACHER WHO SAVED HER SON'S
LIFE.
>> I AM SO GRATEFUL TO THE
TEACHER.
>> SHE SAVED HIS LIFE?
>> SHE DEFINITELY DID.
SHE PULLED HIM AND ANOTHER CHILD
INTO THE CLASSROOM.
>> WHAT ARE COULD HAVE DRIVEN A
MAN TO OPEN FIRE ON DEFENSELESS
CHILDREN?
I AM JOINED BY A PSYCHIATRIST
AND CHIEF MEDICAL CORRESPONDENT
DR. SANJAY GUPTA.
YOU ARE A HIGHLY TRAINED MEDICAL
PROFESSIONAL AND WALK THROUGH
WHAT GOES THROUGH YOUR MIND WHEN
YOU HEAR THE DETAILS OF A MASS
KILLING LIKE THIS IN AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> I THINK FOR MOST OF US HERE
IN LOS ANGELES, YOU THINK ABOUT
YOUR OWN CHILDREN.
THESE EVENTS MAKE YOU WANT TO
HUG YOUR KIDS A BIT TIGHTER
TONIGHT.
I HAVE THREE CHILDREN AS YOU
KNOW, WOLF, AND HAVING COVERED
SO MANY OF THESE TRAGEDIES AS
HAVE YOU, IT IS COMMON FOR LOTS
OF PEOPLE AROUND THE COUNTRY AND
AROUND THE WORLD WHO WERE NOT
INVOLVED WITH THIS TO HAVE
SYMPTOMS AND TO REALLY BE
AFFECTED BY THIS.
IN MANY WAYS.
MANY PEOPLE ARE GOING THROUGH
THE SAME THING.
YOUR COMMUNITY AND THE PEOPLE
AROUND YOU BECOME A REAL SENSE
OF SUPPORT.
IF PEOPLE DEVELOP THESE SYMPTOMS
AND IT CAN LAST FOR DAYS.
IF THEY DEVELOP INTO NIGHTMARES
OR ANXIETY OR DEPRESSION, IT IS
TIME TO SEE SOMEBODY AND GET
HELP.
THERE GOING TO BE PEOPLE WHO
NEED THAT AS A RESULT OF WHAT
HAPPENED.
WOLF, SOMETHING YOU TALKED
ABOUT, WE TALKED ABOUT TOGETHER.
S THAT THIS NOTION THAT WE THINK
OF MENTAL HEALTH AS BEING VAGUE
AND HARDER TO TARGET AND PREDICT
AND HARDER TO TREAT.
MUCH IN THE SAME WAY WE THINK OF
HEART DISEASE OR CANCER, THEY
CAN BE PREDICTED AND CAN BE
TREATED.
ONE OF THE THIRST THINGS THAT
WENT THROUGH MY MIND IS THIS IS
A REMINDER.
>> LISA IS HERE.
SO MANY EXPERTS SAID AFTER OTHER
KILLINGS ALONG THIS LINE OVER
THE YEARS, THERE THESE WARNING
SIGNS AND A LOT OF FOLKS AND
FAMILY MEMBERS DON'T PAY
ATTENTION.
>> THAT'S NOT ENTIRELY FAIR.
I WILL TELL YOU WHY.
I HAVE BEEN IN THIS BUSINESS FOR
25 YEARS.
THERE PLENTY OF FAMILIES WHO ARE
DISTRAUGHT AND HAVE MEMBERS OF
THEIR FAMILY WHO ARE CHILDREN
THAT THEY KNOW ARE DANGEROUS AND
LIVE WITH THIS ANGUISH OF NOT
BEING ABLE TO DO ANYTHING FOR
THEM FOR WEEKS AND MONTHS AND
YEARS.
THE REALITY IS WE DON'T HAVE THE
LEGISLATION THAT A LLLOWS THE
OFFICIALS TO DO WHAT MUST BE
DONE UNTIL THE PERSON COMMITTED
A CRIME AND THAT'S WHAT WHEN
THEY COME TO THE ATTENTION.
IT'S NOT TRUE THAT PEOPLE ARE IN
DENIAL.
>> WHAT ARE THE WARNING SIGNS
THAT PEOPLE SHOULD BE LOOKING TO
START KILLING KIDS?
>> THERE PLENTY OF FAMILIES WHO
DO RESPOND TO THE WARNING SIGNS
AND WILL CALL THE AUTHORITIES.
>> WHAT ARE THEY?
>> THEY WILL SEE A CHILD IS
ANGRY, ISOLATED, CLEARLY
POTENTIALLY RESPONDING TO OUGHT
TORI HALLUCINATIONS AND HEAR
VOICES AND MAYBE A FASCINATION
WITH GUNS AND MAYBE AT A
SHOOTING RANGE.
THEY KNOW SOMETHING IS WRONG.
YOU CAN'T CALL AND SAY MY SON IS
ACTING WEIRD, HE NEEDS HELP.
THEY DON'T HAVE JUSTIFICATION.
IN MOST JURISDICTIONS, IT IS
ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE TO INTERVENE
IN A WAY THAT CAN PROTECT OUR
SOCIETY.
THE LEGISLATION HAS TO BE
CHANGED SO WE ACT BEFORE A
CRIME.
>> SANJAY, YOU STUDY THE BRAIN
ALL THE TIME.
ARE THERE CHEMICAL IMBALANCES
HERE AND CHEMICAL PROBLEMS THAT
COULD CREATE A KILLER LIKE THIS?
>> I THINK SO AND I AGREE WITH
YOUR GUEST AS WELL.
THESE THINGS USED TO BE IN THE
REALM OF THE ANECDOTAL AND THERE
IS EVIDENCE OF WHAT WE CAN SEE
HAPPENING IN THE BRAIN.
THERE MAY BE PEOPLE WHO ARE MORE
PREDISPOSED OR SET UP FOR IT AND
SOMETHING PUSHES THEM OVER THE
EDGE.
IT IS CLEAR AND MOST OF THESE
SITUATIONS.
I THINK THAT TO THINK OF MENTAL
ILLNESS AS A DISEASE AND WHEN
YOU THINK ABOUT IT LIKE THAT, IT
CHANGES EVERYONE'S PERSPECTIVE
AND YOU THINK ABOUT IT MORE LIKE
YOU WOULD THINK OF SOMEONE WITH
HEART PROBLEMS OR CANCER OR
DIABETES.
IT CHANGES PERSPECTIVE OF HOW
YOU POTENTIALLY THINK ABOUT IT
AND GETTING IT DIAGNOSED AND
TREATED.
I AGREE WITH THE GUESTS.
IT'S HARD TO DO.
WE ARE NOT TALKING ABOUT SHOWING
UP AND TAKING A FAMILY MEMBER
AWAY, BUT SOMEONE BEING ABLE TO
TALK ABOUT IT OPENLY AND MAKE
SURE THEY HAVE THE RESOURCES AND
THEY CAN GO SEE SOMEBODY.
IT'S NOT EASY AND NOT EVEN
AVAILABLE FOR MANY PEOPLE AROUND
THE COUNTRY.
>> IF NO ONE COMMITTED A CRIME
AND THERE SIGNS OUT THERE,
LETTERS AND I WANT TO GO OUT
THERE AND KILL PEOPLE AND THEY
ARE GOING TO PRACTICE RANGES, IS
IT USUALLY AN INDICATION OF A
PSYCHIATRIC PROBLEM THAT CAN BE
TREATED FOR EXAMPLE WITH
MEDICINE?
>> SURE IF YOU CAN GET THEM TO
TAKE IT.
USUALLY WHEN YOU HAVE A PERSON
LIKE THAT, THEY WON'T
ACKNOWLEDGE THERE IS ANYTHING
WRONG.
TRY GETTING THEM INTO TREATMENT
AND GETTING THEM TO TAKE THE
PILL.
THEY WON'T DO IT.
NOT EVERYBODY IS OUT THERE DOING
THIS, BUT FOR THOSE WHO DO, IT'S
BECAUSE THEY HAVE MOST LIKELY
REFUSED TREATMENT.
I WILL BET YOU ANYTHING THAT
MOST OF THE PEOPLE THAT WE ARE
TALKING ABOUT AND THE ONE PERSON
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT TODAY WAS
CLEARLY TO HIS FAMILY A DANGER
AND THEY JUST DIDN'T KNOW WHAT
TO DO.
THEY DIDN'T HAVE THE LEGISLATION
AND THAT'S THE PROBLEM, TO BACK
THEM UP TO TAKE ACTION.
I WILL AT THIS.
A NUMBER OF DECADES AGO, WE WERE
FEARFUL THAT PEOPLE BE INTO A
HOSPITAL BECAUSE THEY WERE
DIFFERENT.
WE WANTED TO PROTECT THEM AND WE
ENACTED LAWS TO PROTECT PEOPLE.
WE HAD GONE TOO FAR IN THAT
DIRECTION.
NOW WE HAVE TO FACE THE REALITY.
ACKNOWLEDGE THAT WE HAVE TO STEP
UP OUR WORK AND GETTING PEOPLE
INTO TREATMENT WHEN THEY NEED
IT.
LETTING DOCTORS MAKE THE
DECISIONS AND NOT JUST LAWYERS
AND JUDGES.
>> THANKS FOR THAT EXPERTISE.
SANJAY, THANKS TO YOU AS WELL.
LET'S BRING YOU UP TO DATE ON
WHAT WE KNOW SO FAR IN THE
DEADLY SHOOTING AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE ARE AWAITING A LIVE PRESS
CONFERENCE COMING UP BEFORE THE
TOP OF THE HOUR.
HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW.
27 PEOPLE ARE CONFIRMED DEAD.
20 CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS AND
THE ALLEGED SHOOTER.
WE JUST LEARNED THAT THE MOTHER
OF THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER WAS
FOUND DEAD IN HER SON'S HOME
NEAR THE SCHOOL.
WE ALSO HAVE BEEN TOLD BY A
SOURCE THAT NOBODY HAS BEEN
FOUND IN A HOUSE SEARCHED BY
AUTHORITIES IN HOBOKEN, NEW
JERSEY ALTHOUGH THE SEARCH
CONTINUES.
A LAW ENFORCEMENT SOURCE SAID
THE GUNMAN WAS DRESSED IN WHAT
ARE DESCRIBED AS BLACK BATTLE
FATIGUES AND A MILITARY VEST.
THE SOURCE SAID THE SEMI
AUTOMATIC WEAPON WAS FOUND ALONG
WITH TWO HAND GUNS.
THE CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR DAN
MALLOY HAS BEEN MEETING WITH THE
PARENTS OF THE CHILDREN KILLED
IN THE HORRIBLE TRAGEDY AND
SPOKE OUT A LITTLE WHILE AGO.
>> YOU CAN NEVER BE PREPARED FOR
THIS KIND OF INCIDENT.
WHAT HAPPENED AND WHAT
TRANSPIRED AT THE SCHOOL
BUILDING WILL LEAVE A MARK ON
THIS COMMUNITY AND EVERY FAMILY
IMPACTED.
I ONLY ASK THAT ALL OF OUR
FELLOW CITIZENS IN THE UNITED
STATES AND AROUND THE WORLD WHO
HAVE OFFERED THEIR ASSISTANCE
REMEMBER ALL OF THE VICTIMS IN
THEIR PRAYERS.
TO ALL OF YOU IN THE MEDIA, WE
WILL DO OUR WEST TO KEEP YOU AS
INFORMED AS WE CAN.
AFTER I'M DONE SPEAKING, A
REPRESENTATIVE OF THE STATE
POLICE WILL SPEAK TO YOU AND
GIVE YOU ADDITIONAL INFORMATION.
EARLIER A NUMBER OF OUR
CITIZENS, BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN HAD
THEIR LIFE TAKEN AWAY FROM THEM
AS WELL AS ADULTS WHOSE
RESPONSIBILITY IT WAS TO EDUCATE
AND SUPERVISE THOSE CHILDREN.
>> CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR DAN
MALLOY.
WE ARE AWAITING A PRESS BRIEFING
BY THE STATE POLICE THAT IS
SUPPOSED TO HAPPEN BEFORE THE
TOP OF THE HOUR.
CNN'S ASHLEIGH BANFIELD IS IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT AND JOINS
US ONCE AGAIN.
DESCRIBE A LITTLE BIT MORE OF
THE MOOD OF WHAT YOU ARE FEELING
OVER THERE AND SEEING.
>> Reporter:
>> IT SEEMS EVERY TEN MINUTES
THERE IS ANOTHER DOZEN OR SO
REPORTERS AND TRUCKS AND GEAR
THAT SHOWS UP.
THIS IS OBVIOUSLY AN
EXTRAORDINARY STORY OF NATIONAL
AND INTERNATIONAL IMPORTANCE AS
INTERNATIONAL COUNTRIES START TO
RESPOND TO THIS.
IT'S OBVIOUS FROM THE NUMBER OF
PEOPLE WHO ARE COMING TO REPORT
IT HOW HARD HITTING THIS HAS
BEEN FOR SO MANY PEOPLE.
I WANT TO LET YOU KNOW MECHANICS
OF HOW THINGS ARE PLAYING OUT.
AS NIGHTFALLS OVER THE TOWN, THE
FIREHOUSE HAS BEEN A CENTER FOR
THE PARENTS AND DAN MALLOY, THE
GOVERNOR HIMSELF WHO WAS THE ONE
WHO BROKE IT TO MANY OF THE
PARENTS WHO WERE STILL WAITING
THERE EARLIER THIS EVENING AND
HAD NOT BEEN REUNITED WITH THEIR
CHILDREN.
HE BROKE IT TO THE PARENTS THAT
IF YOU HAVEN'T BEEN REUNITED BY
NOW, IT'S OVER.
THE PROBLEM IS THEY CAN'T MAKE A
POSITIVE AND FORMAL
NOTIFICATION.
AS YOU HEARD THE STATE POLICE
SAYING EARLIER, THE ID PROCESS
IS GOING TO BE AN OVERWHELMING
TASK WITH THAT MANY TINY BODIES
AND THOSE SIX ADULTS AS WELL.
18 LITTLE BODIES THAT HAVE TO BE
IDENTIFIED IS A MASSIVE CRIME
SCENE AND A MASSIVE UNDERTAKING.
IT UNDOUBTEDLY WILL GO ON
THROUGHOUT THE NIGHT.
I WANTED TO LET YOU KNOW ANOTHER
DETAIL.
THE PRINCIPAL IS ONE OF THE
VICTIMS.
SHE HAD JUST THIS FALL
INSTITUTED A BRAND-NEW SECURITY
SYSTEM AT THE SCHOOL IN WHICH
LIKE IN MANY SCHOOLS IF YOU WANT
TO VISIT THE SCHOOL, YOU HAVE TO
HIT A BUZZER.
YOU ARE SEEN BY AN ELECTRONIC
SYSTEM AND BE BUZZED IN.
THOSE LOCKDOWN BY 9:30.
BEFORE 9:30 YOU CAN GO IN AND
OUT.
AFTER 9:30, IT'S THE BUZZ IN
PROCESS.
POSSIBLY HE GOT IN BEFORE THAT
HAPPENED AND WHO KNOWS SINCE HE
A CONNECTION TO THE SCHOOL
ACCORDING TO POLICE THAT IT
WOULD HAVE BEEN AN EASY ACCESS
ANYWAY.
A BASKETBALL COACH AT THE SCHOOL
TOLD HIM HE HAD TWO CHILDREN IN
THE SCHOOL.
THEY ARE OKAY, BUT THEY ARE
TERRIFIED TONIGHT.
COLOR FROM THE PARENTS WHO ARE
COMING OUT OF THE SCHOOL AND ARE
REUNITED WITH THEIR CHILDREN.
IT HAS BEEN DIFFICULT.
OF COURSE THIS REPORTING FROM
OUR SUSAN CANDIOTTI SAYING THE
MOTHER OF THE SHOOTER WAS FOUND
IN HER SON'S RESIDENCE.
TRYING TO PUT THE PIECES
TOGETHER, BUT THE STATE POLICE
ANNOUNCED EARLIER THAT THE
SHOOTER HAD TARGETED A PERSON
THAT HE LIVED WITH.
IT WAS A FAMILY MEMBER HE LIVED
WITH.
WHETHER OR NOT THIS WAS THE
MOTHER'S RESIDENCE, THE
KINDERGARTEN TEACHER WHO
SUFFERED AT THE HANDS OF THE
SHOOTER, WHETHER IT WAS HERS OR
HIS RESIDENCE OR THEY SHARED THE
RESIDENCE IS UNCLEAR.
THAT IS THE SECONDARY CRIME
SCENE HERE IN CONNECTICUT THAT
THEY ARE LOOKING INTO.
AS FAR AS HOW THIS NIGHT WILL
PROGRESS FOR NOT ONLY THE
FAMILIES AFFECTED, BUT THIS
TOWN.
THERE TWO VIGILS THAT WILL GET
UNDER WAY ABOUT 7:00 TONIGHT AT
TWO CHURCHES.
WE HAVE SEEN SIGNS ELSEWHERE FOR
SMALLER VIGILS AS RESTAURANTS
AND BUSINESSES.
DEFINITELY TWO AT TWO OF THE
CHURCHES HERE IN TOWN THAT
SHOULD GET UNDER WAY AT 7:00
TONIGHT.
I CAN'T EVEN DESCRIBE THE MOOD
FOR YOU.
I'M SORRY.
IT'S ONE OF THE THINGS THAT I
THINK WE WILL ALL KNOW WHERE WE
WERE WHEN WE HEARD THE NEWS
BREAK.
>> WE WILL AND YOU LIVE NOT THAT
FAR AWAY IN CONNECTICUT.
GIVE US A LITTLE SENSE OF THIS
NEWTOWN THAT MAYBE OUR VIEWERS
AROUND THE UNITED STATES AND THE
WORLD ARE NOT FAMILIAR WITH THIS
PART OF CONNECTICUT AND THIS
TOWN.
>> IT IS VERY REMOTE.
EARLIER TODAY WHEN THIS WAS
BREAKING, I DESCRIBED IT AS OFF
THE GRID.
VERY REMOTE AND RURAL.
GENTLY ROLLING HILLING AND THICK
WOODED AREAS AND LARGE
PROPERTIES THAT ARE FEW AND FAR
BETWEEN THE POUS HOWS AND SPREAD
OUT.
DEFINITELY THE KIND OF PLACE YOU
WOULD SAY YOU COULD NEVER
IMAGINE IT HAPPENING HERE.
A LOT OF PEOPLE SAY THAT, BUT
THIS IS NOT THE KIND OF PLACE
YOU WOULD THINK SOMETHING WOULD
HAPPEN LIKE THIS.
NOT ONLY THAT, IT'S REMOTE IN
THE SENSE THAT YES, SOME PEOPLE
WHO LIVE HERE DO COMMUTE TO NEW
YORK CITY FOR WORK, BUT IT'S A
LONG COMMUTE.
I COMMUTE AN HOUR EVERY DAY TO
WHERE I LIVE AND THIS IS A SOLID
HOUR AND A HALF.
IT'S A LONGER COMMUTE, BUT THE
PEOPLE WHO LIVE HERE LIVE HERE
FOR THE SAFETY AND THE SECURITY
AND THE TERRIFIC SCHOOL SYSTEM.
THIS IS WHAT YOU HEAR OVER AND
OVER.
WE CAME HERE BECAUSE IT'S THE
PLACE TO BE SAVE AND SECURE AND
ENSURE OUR CHILDREN ARE GOING TO
HAVE A GREAT UPBRINGING.
THAT'S WHAT WE HEAR OVER AND
OVER.
THIS IS SO UNBELIEVABLE THAT
THIS CAN HAPPEN IN A PLACE THAT
IS LIKE A HELL SCENE WHEN YOU
DRIVE THROUGH.
>> THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
WILL COME ONCE AGAIN AND BRIEF
US ON WHAT'S GOING ON.
THEY HAVE BEEN COOPERATIVE AND
NOT PROVIDING NAMES YET.
NOT PROVIDING SPECIFIC
INFORMATION BECAUSE THIS IS AN
ONGOING INVESTIGATION AND ONLY
JUST BEGINNING.
>> YEAH.
JUST IMAGINE THE BULLETS THAT
WERE DESCRIBED TO US EARLIER
TODAY FROM A PARENT WHO WAS IN A
MEETING WITH SOME OF THE SCHOOL
TEACHERS AND PRINCIPAL AND THE
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST AND SAID IT
SOUNDED AS THOUGH THERE WERE AT
LEAST A HUNDRED ROUNDS.
IMAGINE THE AMOUNT OF
INVESTIGATION THAT HAS TO GO ON
BEFORE THEY CAN REALLY PIECE
TOGETHER WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
THEY HAVE TO DO THIS.
OBVIOUSLY WITH THE REPORTS THAT
THE SHOOTER IS DEAD, THAT DOES
HELP IN THE MATTER IN TERMS OF
NOT TRYING TO AMOUNT TO
PROSECUTION AND COLLECT THAT
KIND OF EVIDENCE, BUT LET ME
TELL YOU, 18 LITTLE CHILDREN'S
BODIES ARE IN THAT SCHOOL RIGHT
NOW.
TWO ADDITIONAL CHILDREN WERE
RUSHED TO THE HOSPITAL THAT DIED
IN THE HOSPITAL.
ADULT BODIES ARE HERE AND THE
SHOOTER HIMSELF.
WHAT MIGHT BE DIFFERENT THAN
INVESTIGATING THE COLUMBINE
MASSACRE AS COMPARED TO THIS
ONE, POLICE TELL US IT WAS IN A
CONCENTRATED AREA.
YOU SAW THE REPORT SHOWING THE
LAY OUT OF THE SCHOOL.
IT'S ESSENTIALLY TWO ROOMS WHERE
MOST OF THE KILLINGS TOOK PLACE.
IT'S HARD TO SAY THAT BECAUSE I
KNOW I'M TALKING ABOUT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THAT'S WHAT THEY ARE UP AGAINST
RIGHT NOW.
POSITIVE IDENTIFICATION OF EACH
AND EVERY ONE OF OF THE CHILDREN
AND ADULTS AND THE GRAND AWAY OF
THE BULLETS AND THE FRAGMENTS
AND THE BULLETS AND DISASTER AND
TRY TO COME UP WITH A FORENSIC
STORY.
>> WE WILL STAND BY WITH THE
NEXT BRIEFING.
STAND BY FOR THAT AS WELL.
WE ARE GETTING MORE INFORMATION
AND WE WILL TAKE A QUICK BREAK
AND RESUME OUR SPECIAL COVERAGE
AFTER THIS.
Sometimes, I can't believe the
things I'm able to do.
Without Shriners Hospitals,
my life would be completely
different.
When I was seven,
we found out I had scoliosis.
Everything changed when
they stepped in.
It was like they gave me
my future back.
Tori's life is one of nearly a
million changed
by donations from people
like you.
Send your love to the rescue.
Donate today.
>> >>> WE WILL CARRY THIS AROUND
FOREVER.
THIS TOWN WILL NEVER BE THE
SAME, I'M SURE.
WHAT I FIND MYSELF TALKING TO
OTHER PEOPLE, I CAN'T BELIEVE I
AM COMPARING THIS WITH THE WORST
TRAGEDIES IN THE UNITED STATES.
COLUMBINE AND THE VIRGINIA
SHOOTING.
>> 26 PEOPLE GUNNED DOWN BY A
SHOOTER.
SIX ADULTS AND 20 CHILDREN AGE 5
TO 10.
IN THE SMALL TOWN IN
CONNECTICUT.
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
RARE IF EVER WE SEE THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
CRY DURING AN ADDRESS TO THE
NATION, BUT WE DID SEE THAT
TODAY WHEN PRESIDENT OBAMA SPOKE
TO THE COUNTRY NOT JUST AS THE
COMMANDER IN CHIEF, BUT ALSO AS
A FATHER.
>> I KNOW THERE IS NOTE A PARENT
IN AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS.
MEN AND WOMEN WHO DEVOTED THEIR
LIVES TO HELPING OUR CHILDREN
FULFILL THEIR DREAMS.
SO OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN TODAY.
FOR THE PARENTS AND
GRANDPARENTS, SISTERS AND
BROTHERS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN AND FOR THE FAMILIES OF
THE ADULTS WHO WERE LOST.
>> THERE IS THE WHITE HOUSE
RIGHT NOW.
YOU CAN ONLY IMAGINE THE
CONVERSATION THE PRESIDENT AND
THE FIRST LADY ARE HAVING WITH
THEIR TWO DAUGHTERS RIGHT NOW
LIKE MILLION OF OTHER PARENTS
ARE HAVING WITH THEIR CHILDREN.
YOU SAW THE FLAG HALF-STAFF AT
THE WHITE HOUSE.
THE PRESIDENT ORDERED ALL FLAGS
HALF-STAFF BETWEEN NOW AND
DECEMBER 18th IN MEMORY OF THOSE
KILLED TODAY IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
LET'S BRING IN JESSICA YELLIN.
YOU COVERED THIS AND HAVE YOU
EVER SEEN THE PRESIDENT LIKE
THIS BEFORE?
>> NO, WOLF.
I HAVE NEVER SEEN THE PRESIDENT
SO EMOTIONAL.
HE WAS CRYING NOT JUST IN THAT
CLIP, BUT THROUGHOUT HIS
COMMENTS TODAY.
OPENLY WIPING AWAY TEARS THE
WHOLE TIME AND SPEAKING IN
INCREDIBLY PERSONAL AND
EMOTIONAL TERMS.
THE PRESIDENT UNFORTUNATELY HAS
COME OUT AND ADDRESSED THE
NATION REPEATEDLY AFTER MASS
SHOOTINGS AND WOLF, USUALLY WHEN
HE DOES, HE TRIES TO FIND A
SILVER LINING AND TALKS ABOUT AN
HEROIC ACT BY SOMEBODY WHO WAS
WITH VICTIMS IN THE ROOM OR A
MEDICAL MIRACLE THAT HAPPENED AT
THE HOSPITAL.
A STORY OF AMERICAN RESILIENCE.
TODAY THE FACTS WERE TOO GRIM.
INSTEAD OF PLAYING CONSOLER IN
CHIEF, HE LED THE NATIONS IN
GRIEVING AND EXPRESSING OUR OWN
SADNESS AND IN MOURNING.
YOU CAN SEE THE PRESIDENT ALMOST
STRUGGLE FOR HIS OWN COMPOSURE
AT ONE POINT.
HE TALKED ABOUT HIS GIRLS ARE
SLIGHTLY OLDER THAN THESE KIDS,
BUT YOU SEE HOW MUCH IT HIT HIM
ON A PERSONAL LEVEL AND HOW HE
TALKED ABOUT THIS SORT OF BEING
A MOMENT FOR EVERYBODY TO PUT
ASIDE WHATEVER DIFFERENCES WE
HAVE AND FOCUS ON YOUR OWN LIVES
AND WHAT YOU CAN BE GRATEFUL FOR
AND HELP OTHERS.
I WOULD POINT OUT THAT HE DID
SAY WHILE THIS IS NOT A TIME TO
TALK POLICY AND I WILL QUOTE, WE
ARE GOING TO HAVE TO COMING TO
AND TAKE MEANINGFUL ACTION TO
PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS
REGARDLESS OF THE POLITICS.
WE HAVE TO TO WONDER IF THAT'S
AN INDIRECT REFERENCE TO
FIGHTING FOR SOME OF THOSE
ASSAULT WEAPONS BANNED AND
REINSTATEMENT HE ONCE SUPPORTED
OR OTHER GUN ACTIONS HE ONCE
STOOD FOR AND HAS NOT FOUGHT FOR
IN THE FIRST TERM.
WE WILL FOLLOW-UP ON THAT AT
ANOTHER TIME.
>> ANY INDICATION WHEN THE
PRESIDENT WILL BE GOING TO
CONNECTICUT?
>> NO.
I ASKED AT THE WHITE HOUSE AND
THEY SAID THEY DON'T HAVE ANY
TRAVEL TO ANNOUNCE TO
CONNECTICUT, BUT YOU AND I BOTH
KNOW THAT WILL NO DOUBT MOST
LIKELY APPEAR ON THE PRESIDENT'S
SCHEDULE SOMETIME NEXT WEEK.
I WOULD EXPECT AT SOME POINT HE
WOULD PUT IN CALLS TO EITHER
FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS OR OF
THE SURVIVORS, BUT I ASKED ABOUT
THAT AND THEY HAVE NOTHING TO
REPORT YET.
>> THANKS VERY MUCH.
A POWERFUL MOMENT AT THE WHITE
HOUSE WHERE WE SAW THE PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED STATES REPEATEDLY
WIPING AWAY TEARS AS HE SPOKE
ABOUT THIS MASSACRE AT THIS
SCHOOL IN CONNECTICUT.
WE ARE STANDING BY TO HEAR FROM
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE.
THEY ARE ABOUT TO BRIEF US ONCE
AGAIN ON THE LATEST INFORMATION
COMING IN.
WE WILL HAVE LIVE COVERAGE AFTER
THIS.
[ bells dinging ]
♪ HARK HOW THE BELLS,
SWEET SILVER BELLS ♪
♪ ALL SEEM TO SAY
THROW CARE AWAY ♪
♪ FROM EVERYWHERE,
FILLING THE AIR ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
CHEX PARTY MIX.
EASY 15-MINUTE
HOMEMADE RECIPES
YOU JUST POP IN A MICROWAVE.
LIKE CARAMEL CHOCOLATE
DRIZZLES.
HAPPIER HOLIDAYS.
CHEX PARTY MIX.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
but with ADVAIR,
I'm breathing better.
So now I can be in
the scene.
ADVAIR is
clinically proven to help
significantly improve
lung function.
Unlike most COPD medications,
ADVAIR contains both an
anti-inflammatory
and a
long-acting bronchodilator
working together to help improve
your lung function all day.
ADVAIR won't
replace fast-acting inhalers
for sudden symptoms
and should not be used more
than twice a day.
People with
COPD taking ADVAIR
may have a higher chance
of pneumonia.
ADVAIR may increase your
risk of osteoporosis
and some eye problems.
Tell your doctor
if you have a heart condition
or high blood pressure before
taking ADVAIR.
If you're still
having difficulty breathing,
ask your doctor if including
ADVAIR could help
improve your lung function.
Get your
first full
prescription
free
and save
on refills
at
ADVAIRcopd.com.
But when I was in an accident...
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
So I never missed a beat.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.
CAN YOUR MOISTURIZER DO THAT?
[ Female Announcer ]
DERMATOLOGIST RECOMMENDED
Aveeno HASN OAT FORMULA,
NOW PROVEN
TO BUILD A MOISTURE RESERVE,
SO SKIN CAN REPLENISH ITSELF.
THAT'S HEALTHY SKIN FOR LIFE.
ONLY FROM Aveeno.
>>> LOOKING AT LIVE PICTURES
FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
GETTING READY TO HEAR FROM THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE.
THEY'LL BRIEF US ON THE LATEST
COMMUNICATION COMING IN.
PAUL VANCE WILL TELL US THE
LATEST AS WE AWAIT THIS
BRIEFING.
I WANT TO BRING IN TOM FUENTES,
THE FBI'S FORMER ASSISTANT
DIRECTOR.
TOM, THANKS VERY MUCH FOR
HELPING US IN A SITUATION LIKE
THIS.
I WANT TO CLARIFY WHAT WE
EARLIER LIKE OTHER NEWS
ORGANIZATIONS WERE REPORTING,
THAT THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER WAS
RYAN LANZA, AGE 24.
WE NOW BELIEVE THE SHOOTER WAS
NOT RYAN LANZA.
RYAN LANZA WAS TAKEN INTO
CUSTODY, WE'RE TOLD, EARLIER IN
THE DAY.
THAT PERHAPS HIS BROTHER WAS THE
SUSPECTED SHOOTER, PERHAPS THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE,
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE, WILL
CLARIFY THIS.
BUT WE'RE GETTING MORE
INFORMATION ON WHAT'S GOING ON.
SO WE DO KNOW THAT LANZA'S
MOTHER WAS AMONG THOSE KILLED,
FOUND DEAD AT THE -- AT HER HOME
NEAR THE SCHOOL.
SHE WAS A TEACHER AT THIS
SCHOOL, THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WHEN YOU HEARD ALL THESE DETAILS
COMING IN AND YOU'VE STUDIED
THESE KINDS OF MASS KILLINGS
OVER THE YEARS, WHAT DID YOU
THINK?
>> TO BE FRANK, WOLF, AS I WAS
HEARING THE EARLY REPORTS AND
YOU HAD MANY NEWS ORGANIZATIONS
REPORTING WHO WAS WHERE, WHO WAS
KILLED, WHO WAS THE SHOOTER.
AND THEN WHEN THE POLICE DID
THEIR BRIEFING, THEY WOULDN'T
CONFIRM IT.
THAT TOLD ME IMMEDIATELY THAT
THERE'S A LOT OF FALSE OR
CONFLICTING OR CONFUSING
INFORMATION BEING PUT OUT AND
THE POLICE WERE STILL IN THE
PROCESS OF TRYING TO SORT OUT
EXACTLY WHAT THEY HAD AND
EXACTLY THE IDENTITY OF THAT
SHOOTER.
SO THAT'S WHY OFTENTIMES IN THE
RACE TO GET NEWS OUT FIRST, IT'S
NOT NECESSARILY THE RIGHT STORY.
>> WHAT IS THE ROLE OF THE FBI
IN A MASS MURDER LIKE THIS?
>> IN A CASE OF THIS, WHETHER
IT'S ONE PERSON OR A MASS
MURDER, THE POLICE ARE IN
CHARGE.
SO IN THIS CASE --
>> THE LOCAL POLICE OR THE STATE
POLICE?
>> THAT'S TO BE WORKED OUT BY
AGREEMENT BETWEEN THE CITY,
TOWN, COUNTY AND STATE POLICE
BUT IT'S A LOCAL MATTER.
IT'S FOR THE CONNECTICUT
AUTHORITIES TO DETERMINE WHO'S
IN CHARGE.
IF IT WAS ORGANIZED CRIME OR IF
IT WAS AN ACT OF TERRORISM, IT
WOULD BE A FEDERAL VIOLATION.
AS SOON AS THEY DETERMINE THAT
THE SHOOTER IS NOT A MEMBER OF
SOME NEO-NAZI MILITIA GROUP OR
SOMETHING WHERE HE'S A
TERRORIST --
>> OR A HATE CRIME, THE FBI
WOULD GET INVOLVED.
>> OR A HATE CRIME.
BUT AS SOON AS IT APPEARS IT'S
GOING TO BE A DISTURBED
INDIVIDUAL, THEN PRETTY MUCH THE
POLICE ARE GOING TO BE IN CHARGE
OF THIS.
ALSO, FROM THE LAW ENFORCEMENT
STANDPOINT, IT REALLY IS NOT
CRITICAL AT THAT POINT WHOSE
CASE IT WILL BE.
IT DOESN'T APPEAR THERE'S GOING
TO BE A PROSECUTION IF THE
SHOOTER -- THE OFFENDER IS DEAD
AND NO OTHER PARTICIPANTS OR
CO-CONSPIRATORS ARE IDENTIFIED.
IN THIS CASE, THE POLICE, THE
FBI, THE ATF, ALL OTHER AGENCIES
FROM THE AREA THAT WILL BE
WORKING ON THIS WILL BE WORKING
VERY CLOSELY TOGETHER BUT IT
WILL BE UNDER THE COMMAND OF THE
LOCAL AUTHORITIES.
>> BECAUSE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE SAYS THE SHOOTER IS DEAD,
NO ONE SHOT AT THE SHOOTER.
WE ASSUME THE SHOOTER WOUND UP
KILLING HIMSELF AFTER KILLING
ALL THESE KUNG KIDS AND KILLING
THE ADULTS.
BUT IF OTHERS MAY HAVE KNOWN
ABOUT THESE PLANS, THERE COULD
BE CRIMINAL PROSECUTIONS OF
OTHERS WHO MAY HAVE KNOWN ABOUT
IT.
>> THERE COULD BE.
BUT OFTEN THERE'S NOT IN THESE
CASES.
YOU MAY HAVE OTHER MEMBERS OF
THE FAMILY OR FRIENDS OR MAYBES
WHO SAY, WELL, I KNEW HE WASN'T
NORMAL, I KNEW HE HAD SOME
PROBLEMS BUT I DIDN'T THINK HE
WOULD GO THIS FAR, I DIDN'T KNOW
HE HAD GUNS, DIDN'T KNOW HE WAS
PLANNING THE EVENT.
BUT THAT'S PART OF WHAT THE
INVESTIGATION IS GOING TO BE ALL
ABOUT IN THE DAYS AHEAD IS
OBTAINING HIS E-MAIL RECORDS AND
PHONE RECORDS TO SEE WHO HAS HE
BEEN IN CONTACT WITH AND WHAT
DID HE TELL THEM?
WHAT DO OTHERS THAT KNEW HIM --
WHAT DO THEY KNOW ABOUT HIS
THOUGHT PROCESS LEADING UP TO
THE EVENT.
>> YOU'VE BEEN INVOLVED IN LAW
ENFORCEMENT YOUR WHOLE LIFE.
ANYTHING WE CAN LEARN FROM THIS
AND MOVE FORWARD TO TRY TO MAKE
SURE IT DOESN'T HAPPEN AGAIN?
>> NO.
>> IT'S GOING TO HAPPEN AGAIN?
>> IT'S GOING TO HAPPEN AGAIN.
WE DON'T CHANGE ANYTHING OF THE
BASICS.
WE HAVEN'T MADE THE IMPROVEMENTS
OF OUR MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEM TO
TAKE CARE OF PEOPLE WHO ARE
SEVERELY DISTURBED.
WE HAVEN'T DONE ANYTHING TO
PREVENT THE SEVERELY DISTURBED
FROM OBTAINING THE WEAPONS THAT
ARE SO PREVALENT IN OUR SOCIETY.
AS LONG AS YOU HAVE DISTURBED
PEOPLE ABLE TO OBTAIN WEAPONS
AND ACT OUT WITH THOSE WEAPO
WEAPONS --
>> A LOT OF FOLKS WILL SAY THAT
ASSAULT WEAPONS ARE TOO
AVAILABLE, TOO EASY TO GET.
>> WHAT WE SAY NOW IS WE CAN'T
TALK ABOUT IT.
EVERYBODY'S IN MOURNING.
IT'S TOO SOON, IT'S NOT
APPROPRIATE.
SO LATER WHEN IT IS APPROPRIATE,
WE DON'T CARE.
AND NOTHING CHANGES.
AND I HAD A DAUGHTER AT VIRGINIA
TECH DOWN THE HALL FROM THE
FIRST SHOOTING, PEOPLE WERE
KILLED IN A ROOM TEN ROOMS AWAY.
WHAT'S CHANGED IN THE STATE OF
VIRGINIA?
NOT ONE THING.
>> YOUR DAUGHTER OKAY?
>> YES.
>> THANK GOD FOR THAT.
TOM, THANKS VERY MUCH FOR COMING
IN.
BRIAN TODD IS BRINGING US SOME
OF THE MOST EMOTIONAL REACTION
COMING IN SO FAR TODAY.
>> Reporter: THE ACCOUNT OF A
YOUNG BOY SAID TO BE DELIVERING
AN ATTENDANCE REPORT TO THE
OFFICE AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL WHEN THE SHOOTING TOOK
PLACE IS SURREAL.
>> I SAW THE BOARDS GOING PAST
THE HALL THAT I WAS RIGHT NEXT
TO.
AND THEN A TEACHER PULLED ME
INTO HER CLASSROOM.
>> Reporter: HE SAID HE HEARD A
SOUND LIKE SOMEONE KICKING A
DOOR.
HIS MOTHER, CLINGING TO HIM, HAD
WORDS OF THANKS.
>> I'M JUST SO GRATEFUL TO THE
TEACHER WHO SAVED HIM.
>> YOU THINK THE TEACHER SAVED
HIS LIFE.
>> SHE DEFINITELY DID.
HE HAD BULLETS GOING BY HIM AND
SHE GRABBED HIM AND ANOTHER
CHILD AND PULLED THEM INTO A
CLASSROOM.
>> Reporter: BRENDAN MURRAY, A
FOURTH-GRADER, DESCRIBED THE
CHAOS.
>> I WAS IN THE GYM AT THE TIME.
SO THE TEACHERS -- WE HEAR LOTS
OF BANGS.
AND WE THOUGHT THAT IT WAS THE
CUSTODIAN KNOCKING STUFF DOWN.
WE HEARD SCREAMING.
AND SO WE WENT TO THE WALL AND
WE SAT DOWN AND THEN THE POLICE
CAME IN.
IT'S LIKE, IS HE IN HERE?
THEN HE RAN OUT.
AND OUR TEACHER -- SOMEBODY
YELLED, GET TO A SAFE PLACE.
SO WE WENT INTO THE CLOSET IN
THE GYM AND WE SAT THERE FOR A
LITTLE WHILE.
THEN THE POLICE WERE KNOCKING ON
THE DOOR AND THEY'RE LIKE, WE'RE
EVACUATING PEOPLE.
>> Reporter: CNN IS ONLY AIRING
SOUND OF CHILDREN WHOSE PARENTS
GAVE PERMISSION.
AS ONE WOMAN WALKED AWAY FROM
THE SCHOOL, SHE WAS HEARD
CRYING, WHY, WHY?
A POLICEMAN WAS HEARD SAYING, IT
WAS THE WORST THING HE'D SEEN IN
HIS CAREER.
A NURSE FROM NEARBY DANBURY
HOSPITAL DESCRIBED THE SCENE
THERE AS PARENTS WAITED FOR WORD
ABOUT THEIR CHILDREN.
>> THESE PARENTS WERE WAITING
FOR THEIR CHILDREN TO COME OUT.
THEY THOUGHT THAT THEY WERE
STILL ALIVE.
THERE'S 20 PARENTS THAT WERE
JUST TOLD THAT THEIR CHILDREN
ARE DEAD.
IT WAS AWFUL.
>> Reporter: THE FATHER OF A
YOUNG GIRL WHO SURVIVED WAS JUST
TRYING TO PROCESS IT ALL.
>> IT WAS SHOCKING.
>> HERE HE IS, THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT, DAN MALLOY.
>> WE HAVE HEARD FROM IN THE
ENSUING HOURS SINCE THIS
UNSPEAKABLE AND TRAGIC EVENT
OCCURRED HERE.
AS YOU KNOW, THERE ARE A NUMBER
OF VICTIMS, TEACHERS, SUPPORT
PERSONNEL IN THE BUILDING AND
CHILDREN, BEAUTIFUL, BEAUTIFUL
CHILDREN WHO HAD SIMPLY COME TO
SCHOOL TO LEARN AND THEIR DAY
ENDED A VERY DIFFERENT WAY THAN
ANY OF US COULD POSSIBLY HAVE
IMAGINED.
AND QUITE FRANKLY AS WE STAND
HERE TODAY, STILL CAN'T IMAGINE
WHAT TRANSPIRED THERE.
EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY
TODAY.
IT'S TOO EARLY TO SPEAK OF
RECOVERY.
BUT EACH PARENT, EACH SIBLING,
EACH MEMBER OF THE FAMILY HAS TO
UNDERSTAND THAT CONNECTICUT --
WE'RE ALL IN THIS TOGETHER.
WE'LL DO WHATEVER WE CAN TO
OVERCOME THIS EVENT.
WE WILL GET THROUGH IT.
BUT THIS IS A TERRIBLE TIME FOR
THIS COMMUNITY AND FOR THESE
FAMILIES.
OUR POLICE PERSONNEL AND OTHERS
ARE DOING THE UTMOST TO CLEAR
THIS SITUATION AS SOON AS
POSSIBLE AND TO RETURN THESE
CHILDREN TO THEIR PARENTS OR
THESE LOVED ONES TO THEIR FELLOW
LOVED ONES AS QUICKLY AS
POSSIBLE.
AND WE'LL WORK WITH ALL OF THE
RESIDENTS OF THIS COMMUNITY AND
CONNECTICUT TO MAKE SURE THAT WE
DO, IN FACT, GET THROUGH THIS.
I WAS MAYOR OF STAMFORD ON 9/11
WHEN OUR STATE LOST MANY OF ITS
CITIZENS AND I LOST A NUMBER OF
MY FELLOW CITIZENS AND FRIENDS.
I NEVER THOUGHT THAT IN A PUBLIC
CAREER THAT I WOULD HAVE TO FACE
THESE KINDS OF CIRCUMSTANCES OR
THAT THEY WOULD VISIT THEMSELVES
UPON THIS COMMUNITY OR THE
PEOPLE OF CONNECTICUT.
WE'LL GET THROUGH THIS.
AND OUR PRAYERS AT THIS TIME
HAVE TO GO OUT TO THE FAMILIES.
AND SO AS I BEGAN BY THANKING
THOSE WHO HAVE EXPRESSED THEIR
DESIRES TO BE HELPFUL, THE
NUMBER ONE WAY TO BE HELPFUL IS
TO SAY A PRAYER OR SEND A BEST
WISH OR TO BE THINKING OF THESE
INDIVIDUALS WHO HAVE SUFFERED SO
MIGHTILY TODAY.
THANK YOU.
>> THAT'S THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT, DAN MALLOY.
I THINK WE'RE GOING TO BE
HEARING FROM LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE AS WELL FROM THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE.
IF HE COMES TO THOSE
MICROPHONES, OF COURSE, WE'RE
ANXIOUS TO HEAR WHAT HE SAYS.
IT LOOKS LIKE HE'S NOT SPEAKING
OVER THERE.
BUT WE WILL CONTINUE TO MONITOR
WHAT'S GOING ON.
A HORRIFIC, HORRIFIC DAY IN
CONNECTICUT AS WE'RE WATCHING
THIS STORY UNFOLD.
THE BREAKING NEWS CONTINUING TO
EXPLODE NOT ONLY HERE IN THE
UNITED STATES BUT AROUND THE
WORLD.
W
WE WANT TO WELCOME OUR VIEWERS
FROM AROUND THE WORLD.
THE STATE POLICE LIEUTENANT,
PAUL VANCE, HE TELLS ME
AUTHORITIES ARE INTERVIEWING
EVERYONE WHO POSSIBLY HAD ANY
CONNECTION TO THE SUSPECTED
GUNMAN.
KATE BOLDUAN IS HERE HELPING US
WITH OUR COVERAGE AS WELL.
THIS IS A STORY THAT CONTINUES
TO RESONATE FOR PARENTS,
GRANDPARENTS, LOVED ONES,
EVERYONE, THOSE KIDS, AND A
SITUATION LIKE THIS UNFOLDS,
IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE.
>> EVERYONE HAS BEEN AFFECTED BY
THIS AND WILL CONTINUE TO BE
AFFECTED BY THIS.
THE GOVERNOR, I THINK, SAID IT
WELL AND VERY SIMPLY PUT THAT
EVIL HAS VISITED THAT TOWN
TODAY.
I THINK THAT'S ABSOLUTELY AT
LEAST ONE THING THAT WE CAN ALL
BE SURE OF THAT HAS HAPPENED.
THE INVESTIGATION IS UNFOLDING.
THE GRIEVING, THOUGH, IS ONLY
BEGINNING.
A CHURCH VIGIL, MANY ARE UNDER
WAY AND DUE TO START SOON IN
NEWTOWN WHERE THIS TRAGEDY HAS
UNFOLDED.
LET'S BRING IN OUR JASON
CARROLL, WHO IS ON THE GROUND
THERE.
JASON, ARE YOU AT THE SITE OF
THE VIGIL?
>> Reporter: THAT'S CORRECT.
THAT VIGIL SET TO TAKE PLACE
JUST ABOUT 7:00 HERE AT ST. ROSE
LIMA CHURCH.
I SPOKE TO THE DEE CAN HERE
EARLIER.
IT WAS AN EMOTIONAL DISCUSSION.
HE TOLD ME THROUGHOUT THE DAY,
AT LEAST 100 PEOPLE HAVE COME
THROUGH THE DOORS AT THE CHURCH
HERE TRYING TO FIND PEACE,
LOOKING FOR ANSWERS, TRYING TO
FIND SOME SORT OF COMFORT.
SO HE HAS BEEN DOING THAT
THROUGHOUT THE DAY.
AND THIS IS PERSONAL TO HIM.
IT'S PERSONAL TO THIS COMMUNITY.
HE TOLD ME THAT A NUMBER OF THE
VICTIMS WENT TO CHURCH HERE.
THIS IS WHERE THESE CHILDREN HAD
THEIR FIRST COMMUNION.
THIS IS WHERE THEY SAT IN THE
PEWS WITH THEIR PARENTS AND
LISTENED TO CERTAINLIENS.
HE KNEW SOME OF THE VICTIMS AND
HE TALKED ABOUT THAT JUST A
LITTLE EARLIER.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> THIS IS A VERY TIGHT-KNIT
COMMUNITY, IT'S A LARGE AND
DYNAMIC PARISH.
EVERYBODY KNOWS EVERYBODY HERE.
I DON'T KNOW FOR SURE, BUT I'M
SURE THAT QUITE A FEW OF THE
KIDS THAT WE LOST TODAY ARE IN
THIS PARISH.
>> Reporter: AND I CAN ALSO TELL
YOU THAT IN TERMS OF WHAT PEOPLE
ARE ASKING IS THERE ARE LOTS OF
QUESTIONS.
THEY'RE ASKING QUESTIONS, WHY?
WHY DID SOMETHING LIKE THIS
HAPPEN?
AND HE SAID BECAUSE OF THE
NEWNESS OF IT ALL, THERE'S NO
WAY TO TRY TO ANSWER THAT WITH
SOMETHING PROFOUND.
BUT HE DID SAY THIS, HE SAID,
QUOTE, THERE ARE SOME QUESTIONS
THAT ARE ONLY MEANT FOR GOD TO
ANSWER.
AND HE SAID, THAT IS WHAT HE'S
TELLING PEOPLE.
LISTEN TO A LITTLE BIT MORE IN
TERMS OF WHAT HE HAD TO SAY
ABOUT THAT.
>> I HEARD ONE OF THE VICTIMS --
I'M NOT SURE ABOUT IT.
BUT I HEARD THAT ONE OF THE
VICTIMS -- RECENTLY SHE -- I
THINK IT WAS BIRTHDAY MONEY.
SHE GOT HER BIRTHDAY MONEY.
SHE DONATED IT TO THE PARISH TO
GIVE TO THE HURRICANE SANDY
VICTIMS.
6 YEARS OLD.
SO THAT'S -- THAT MAKES IT VERY,
VERY PERSONAL AND VERY INTIMATE.
>> Reporter: AND THAT WAS WHEN
HE WAS TELLING ME ABOUT A
6-YEAR-OLD GIRL, ONE OF THE
VICTIMS, HE SAYS, WHO WENT TO
THIS CHURCH.
HE USED TO LOOK AT THIS GIRL
EVERY SUNDAY.
SO YOU CAN IMAGINE HOW PAINFUL
IT IS FOR HIM, HOW PAINFUL IT IS
FOR THIS COMMUNITY.
ONCE AGAIN, THE VIGIL IS
EXPECTED TO TAKE PLACE HERE AT
JUST ABOUT 7:00.
WHEN I ASKED WHAT WILL BE
HAPPENING, HE SAID, THIS IS
UNLIKE ANY VIGIL OBVIOUSLY
THEY'VE EVER HAD IN THE PAST.
AND A LOT OF IT'S GOING TO BE
OFF THE CUFF.
THERE WILL BE A MASS.
EXPECTED TO LAST FOR ABOUT AN
HOUR.
HE SAID ALL WE CAN CONTINUE TO
DO THROUGHOUT THE NIGHT,
THROUGHOUT THE COMING DAYS AND
THE M COOING WEEKS IS BE THERE
AND TRY TO PROVIDE COMFORT TO
THESE GRIEVING FAMILIES.
>> JASON, IT SEEMS THE DEE CAN
HIMSELF IS STRUGGLING FOR WORDS
AND HOW TO COPE WITH THIS.
HAS HE AT ALL BEEN CONTACTED BY
ANY OF THE FAMILIES, ANYONE FROM
THE SCHOOL?
IT SEEMS IT IS A VERY SMALL
COMMUNITY THERE.
>> Reporter: HE HAS.
HE HAS BEEN IN CONTACT WITH THE
FAMILIES.
SOME OF THE OTHER PRIESTS HERE
HAVE BEEN DOWN AT THE FIREHOUSE
CONSOLING THE FAMILIES
THROUGHOUT THE DAY.
AND HE HAS CHILDREN HIMSELF.
SO THIS IS PERSONAL FOR HIM.
THEY DID NOT GO TO THIS
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL BUT TO ANOTHER
ONE.
BUT HE KNEW THESE CHILDREN.
HE KNEW THE FACULTY AT THE
SCHOOL.
THE FACULTY SAT IN THESE PEWS AS
WELL.
AND SO NOT ONLY DOES HE HAVE TO
PROVIDE COMFORT TO SOME OF THE
VICTIMS, THE VICTIMS' FAMILIES,
BUT HE ALSO HAS TO TRY AND FIND
UNDERSTANDING HIMSELF BECAUSE IN
HIS WORDS, HE'S GOT TO BE THEIR
ROCK.
HE'S GOT TO BE THE PERSON HERE
PROVIDING THE SUPPORT, WHICH IS
DIFFICULT FOR HIM.
HE SAID WHAT HE'S GOING TO DO IS
TAKE A LITTLE BIT OF A BREAK, GO
HOME, HUG HIS OWN DAUGHTER, GIVE
THANKS AND COME BACK AND PROVIDE
THE SUPPORT THAT IS SO BADLY
NEEDED HERE.
>> BEING THAT ROCK, MUCH EASIER
SAID THAN DONE AT A TIME LIKE
THIS WHEN SUCH UNSPEAKABLE
TRAGEDY HAS HIT SUCH A SMALL
COMMUNITY.
JASON CARROLL LIVE OUTSIDE WHERE
A VIGIL WILL BE STARTING IN JUST
ABOUT AN HOUR FROM NOW.
JASON CARROLL, THANKS SO MUCH.
>> WHAT A POWERFUL, POWERFUL
REPORT.
LET ME JUST REMIND OUR VIEWERS
WHAT'S GOING ON.
FOR THOSE WHO MAY JUST BE TUNING
IN, AROUND 9:30, 9:40 A.M. THIS
MORNING, A MAN WENT INTO A SMALL
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AND BEGAN KILLING
PEOPLE.
26 PEOPLE ALL TOGETHER.
SIX ADULTS AND 20 CHILDREN.
THIS IS A SMALL ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
FEWER THAN 600 CHILDREN IN THAT
SCHOOL.
ONLY GRADES KINDERGARTEN THROUGH
FOURTH GRADE INSIDE.
WE HAVE NO IDEA THE MOTIVE, WHAT
WAS BEHIND WHAT WAS GOING ON.
26 PEOPLE WERE KILLED AND THEN
THE SHOOTER, WE BELIEVE, KILLED
HIMSELF.
SEPARATELY, THE MOTHER OF THE
SHOOTER, WE BELIEVE, WAS KILLED
SEPARATELY AT A HOME NOT FAR
AWAY FROM THIS SCHOOL.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT LIVE PICTURES
COMING IN FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, RIGHT NOW.
THE POLICE ARE CONTINUING THEIR
INVESTIGATION.
AND I SUSPECT THE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE WILL BE BRIEFING US
FAIRLY SOON.
THESE ARE PICTURES COMING IN
FROM THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
SUSAN CANDIOTTI IS ON THE SCENE
FOR US AS SHE'S BEEN NOW FOR
SEVERAL HOURS.
UPDATE OUR VIEWERS.
WHAT'S THE LATEST, SUSAN?
>> Reporter: THE LATEST IS THAT
IN ADDITION TO TRYING TO PIECE
ALL OF THIS TOGETHER TO FIND OUT
THE MOTIVE, MORE ABOUT THE
SHOOTER, WE ALSO UNDERSTAND THAT
FOR A FEW HOURS NOW, POLICE TOOK
INTO CUSTODY OR AT LEAST TOOK
SOMEONE IN FOR QUESTIONING
SOMEONE WHO'S BEEN IDENTIFIED TO
US BY SOURCES AS A BROTHER OF
THE DEAD SHOOTER HERE INVOLVED
IN THIS SCHOOL INCIDENT, THE
SXOOL SHOOTING.
AND THEY'RE ASKING HIM QUESTIONS
ABOUT HIS BROTHER.
HE IS NOT BEING CALLED A SUSPECT
AT THIS TIME.
BUT THEY DO WANT TO TRY TO FIND
OUT AT THE VERY MINIMUM WHAT
INFORMATION HE MAY HAVE ABOUT
THE DEAD GUNMAN HERE AT THE
SCHOOL.
ALSO TRYING TO FIND OUT MORE
ABOUT THE MOTHER OF THE SHOOTER
WHO YOU KNOW HAS BEEN IDENTIFIED
AS A SCHOOLTEACHER AND SHE WAS
FOUND DEAD, WE ARE TOLD BY
SOURCES, AT A RESIDENCE NEARBY
THE SCHOOL HERE.
SO ALL OF THESE PIECES AND PARTS
OF THE PUZZLE BEING WORKED OUT
AT THIS MOMENT BY INVESTIGATORS
TO TRY AND FIND OUT EXACTLY WHAT
LED INTO THIS AND WHAT THE TIME
LINE WAS AS WELL, WOLF.
FOR EXAMPLE, WAS THE MOTHER SHOT
BEFORE ALL OF THIS BEGAN?
WE DON'T KNOW.
WOLF?
>> WE CAN ONLY IMAGINE IF THE
SHOOTER, THOUGH, SUSAN, WAS
FOUND DEAD AT THE SCENE, NO ONE
SHOT HIM, WE ASSUME THE SHOOTER
COMMITTED SUICIDE.
AND ALL THAT TOOK PLACE BETWEEN
9:30 AND 10:00 A.M. OR SO,
APPROXIMATELY 20 MINUTES OR HALF
AN HOUR.
THE ASSUMPTION I HAVE IS THAT
THE SHOOTER PRESUMABLY KILLED
HIS MOTHER AT THE HOME BEFORE
DRIVING OVER TO THE SCHOOL.
>> Reporter: THAT SEEMS TO BE,
OF COURSE, A FAIR ASSUMPTION
HERE.
BUT NO ONE OFFICIALLY IS SAYING
THAT.
IN FACT, THEY HAVEN'T EVEN
OFFICIALLY RELEASED THE NAME OF
THE GUNMAN IN THIS CASE.
WE DO KNOW FROM SOURCES THEY
RECOVERED THE AT LEAST THREE
WEAPONS FROM THE SCENE.
TWO OF THEM HANDGUNS, INCLUDING
A GLOCK AND A SIG SAUER.
AND ANOTHER ONE, A SEMIAUTOMATIC
WEAPON IDENTIFIED AS A .223
BUSHMASTER.
WE DON'T KNOW HOW MANY BULLETS
WERE FIRED.
A NUMBER OF WITNESSES SAY THERE
WERE A LOT OF BULLETS THAT WERE
HEARD.
WE ALSO DO NOT KNOW -- TRYING TO
FIND OUT, FOR EXAMPLE, HOW MUCH
AMMUNITION THE SHOOTER CAME TO
THE SCHOOL WITH AND DID HE HAVE
ANY EXTRA MAGAZINES WITH HIM,
GUN MAGAZINES, AMMO?
THOSE ARE THE KINDS OF THINGS
WE'RE ALSO TRYING TO FIND OUT,
WOLF.
>> WE'LL BE GETTING MORE
INFORMATION IN THE HOURS TO
COME, SUSAN, THANKS VERY MUCH.
TOM FOREMAN IS JOINING US NOW.
HE'S BEEN LOOKING AT THE LAYOUT
OF THIS L SKOO.
WHAT ARE YOU SEEING, TOM?
>> SUSAN WAS RAISING A GOOD
POINT AS YOU HAVE.
PIECING ALL THIS TOGETHER IS
GRIM AND DIFFICULT, DIFFICULT
WORK BECAUSE THERE ARE SO MANY
MOVING PARTS TO THIS EQUATION.
THAT'S WHAT THE INVESTIGATORS
ARE TRYING TO DO RIGHT NOW.
IN MORE THAN 30 YEARS OF
COVERING MASSACRES AND SCHOOL
SHOOTINGS, I'VE SEEN THIS HAPPEN
MANY TIMES.
THE EARLY HOURS, IT'S HARD TO
KNOW EXACTLY WHAT THE TIME LINE
WAS, EXACTLY HOW THINGS
UNFOLDED.
WE'RE PIECING IT TOGETHER AS
BEST WE CAN AS WELL.
SO TAKE THIS TIME LINE AS BEING
A BIT LOOSE BUT WE'LL WORK OUR
WAY THROUGH IT.
ABOUT 9:30 THIS MORNING IN THIS
SCHOOL, CLASSES WERE UNDER WAY
HERE.
THEY HAD A GOOD CROWD IN THERE,
ABOUT 600 STUDENTS IN THE
SCHOOL, 50 FACULTY MEMBERS.
AND AT THAT TIME, A MEETING HAD
JUST BROKEN OUT UP IN THE
BEGINNING OF THE SCHOOL HERE.
A SMALL MEETING WITH THE
PRINCIPAL, VICE PRINCIPAL, THE
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST AND A FEW
ADULTS UP HERE IN A ROOM NEAR
THE OFFICE.
SCHOOL STARTED AT 9:05.
AT 9:30, HALF AN HOUR UNDER WAY,
THEY'D BE GOING UP THERE.
AT 9:40-ISH, BEST WE CAN TELL,
IT'S DIFFERENT DEPENDING ON WHOM
YOU TALK TO, SOMEWHERE AROUND
9:40 IS WHEN IT WOULD APPEAR
THAT THIS GUNMAN ENTERS THE
BUILDING.
HOW?
WE DON'T REALLY KNOW.
POLICE HAVE SPENT A LOT OF TIME
TODAY -- KEEP SEE PG PICTURES OF
A BLACK CAR.
THEY'VE BEEN LOOKING AT THAT CAR
RIGHT HERE.
IF THAT IS CONNECTED TO THE
CRIME AS WE THINK AND BASED ON
WHAT THE EYEWITNESSES HAVE SAID,
THAT WOULD SUGGEST THE GUNMAN
CAME IN THROUGH THE FRONT DOOR
HERE.
THIS LITTLE RED PART HERE IS A
COVERED WALKWAY.
HE WOULD HAVE COME IN HERE.
AND EVERYTHING TRANSPIRED IN
THIS AREA.
AS SOON AS HE CAME IN, FROM ALL
WE HEAR FROM VARIOUS PEOPLE
THERE, PEOPLE THROUGHOUT THIS
ENTIRE BUILDING STARTED HEARING
SHOTS BEING FIRED.
SOME OF THEM THOUGHT IT SOUNDED
LIKE HAMMERING.
SOME OF THEM HEARD LOUD BANGS.
SOME OF THEM ALSO KNEW WHAT IT
WAS.
BY 9:41, WE HAD CALLS GOING IN
TO 911.
THE PRINCIPAL, VICE PRINCIPAL
AND SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST WHO WERE
IN THAT MEETING CAME OUT AND
WENT TOWARD THE GUNFIRE,
ACCORDING TO A WITNESS.
THEY HEADED TOWARD IT BUT ONLY
THE VICE PRINCIPAL RETURNED AND
THE VICE PRINCIPAL WAS WOUNDED
IN THE LEG OR THE FOOT.
IT'S NOT CLEAR WHICH.
NONETHELESS, AT THIS POINT,
EVERYTHING IS CLEARLY GETTING
VERY TENSE BECAUSE PEOPLE KNOW
SOMETHING IS GOING ON THAT'S
VERY BAD THERE.
NOW, THE TIME LINE GETS EVEN
LOOSER AT THIS POINT BECAUSE WE
DON'T KNOW HOW THE PROGRESS OF
THE GUNFIRE WENT.
WE KNOW THAT THE PEOPLE WHO WERE
IN THIS MEETING AND WITNESSES UP
HERE SAID THEY HEARD A
TREMENDOUS NUMBER OF SHOTS.
WE KNOW THEY HEARD YELLING AND
SCREAMING.
AUTHORITIES SAY THE ACTUAL
SHOOTING HAPPENED OVER A
RELATIVELY SHORT PERIOD OF TIME
FOR ALL THE SHOTS THAT
APPARENTLY WERE FIRED.
AND THE GUNMAN DID NOT ROAM
AROUND.
BUT, AGAIN, GENERALLY FROM ALL
ACCOUNTS, STAYED RIGHT IN THIS
AREA IN TWO ROOMS IN TERMS OF
WHERE ALL THE SHOOTING HAPPENED.
AND IN FACT, HE WAS FOUND IN ONE
OF THOSE ROOMS.
NOW, AT THE SAME TIME THAT ALL
THIS IS HAPPENING -- AGAIN, BEAR
IN MIND, THIS IS A VERY LOOSE
TIME LINE WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
HERE.
THE TEACHERS ARE TRYING TO
PROTECT STUDENTS ALL OVER THIS
SCHOOL.
IN SOME CASES, THEY SEEM TO BE
TRYING TO GET SOME OF THEM OUT.
IN MANY OTHER CASES, THEY'RE
TRYING TO HIDE THEM WITHIN THE
SCHOOL.
THEY'RE LOCKING THE DOORS, GOING
INTO LOCKDOWN AS PEOPLE
DESCRIBED IT AND SAY THEY HAVE
TO STAY THERE AND BE SAFE.
THAT'S NOT REALLY CLEAR BECAUSE
SOME OF THE STUDENTS ARE TALKING
ABOUT BEING EVACUATED AND IT'S
NOT CLEAR IF A TEACHER TRIED TO
LEAD THEM OUT OR AS, IN THIS
CASE, LAW OFFICERS WERE LEADING
THEM OUT WHICH HAPPENED A LITTLE
BIT LATER.
THE BOTTOM LINE IS, THOUGH, AS
THIS PROGRESSES, THE GUNFIRE
SEEMS TO HAVE STOPPED.
AT SOME POINT LAW OFFICERS
ARRIVED ON THE SCENE FROM BOTH
THE LOCAL POLICE AND THE STATE
POLICE, LOCAL POLICE SAID FO THE
STATE POLICE, WE KNOW WE HAVE A
SERIOUS ISSUE HERE.
IT IS NOT CLEAR WHEN IN THIS
PROCESS THE GUNMAN DIES
SOMEWHERE UP IN HERE.
WE KNOW FROM LAWMEN THAT NONE OF
THE OFFICERS FIRED A SHOT DURING
THIS TIME.
AS YOU SUGGESTED A MOMENT AGO,
WOLF, THAT WOULD SUGGEST THAT
SOMEHOW HE SHOT HIMSELF AT THAT
POINT.
BUT WE DO KNOW THAT WHEN THESE
OFFICERS ARRIVE AT THE SCHOOL,
THEY QUICKLY SEALED THE ENTIRE
SCHOOL OFF AND THEY SPREAD INTO
THE SCHOOL RAPIDLY, LOCKING DOWN
EVERYTHING.
MAKING SURE THERE'S NO OTHER
GUNMAN.
AND FRANKLY LOOKING FOR THOSE
CHILDREN WHO ARE HIDING IN
THERE.
AND I KNOW FROM PAST SCHOOL
SHOOTINGS, THIS CAN BE A VERY,
VERY DANGEROUS TIME SIMPLY
BECAUSE THESE OFFICERS ARE
POSSIBLY LOOKING FOR A GUNMAN
BUT THEY'RE SUDDENLY WALKING
PAST CLOSETS VERY OPENING AND
PEOPLE ARE COMING OUT AND THEY
WALK PAST DOORBAYWAYS AND PEOPLE
EMERGE BEHIND THEM.
IT'S A VERY DANGEROUS, TENSE
TIME WHEN OFFICERS HAVE TO BE
VERY PROFESSIONAL AND
DISCIPLINED AND MAKE SURE
SOMETHING AWFUL BEYOND THE
HORRID EVENT THAT'S ALREADY
HAPPENED DOES NOT OCCUR.
BOTTOM LINE, THOSE OFFICERS WENT
IN, THEY SECURED THE SCHOOL,
THEY STARTED CLEARING THE KIDS
OUT OF THE SCHOOL.
AND WHEN ALL IS SAID AND DONE,
THIS WHOLE EVENT PROBABLY TOOK
20 TO 25 MINUTES, MAYBE 30,
WOLF, FROM A NORMAL MORNING AT
SCHOOL TO THIS TREMENDOUSLY
AWFUL EVENT THAT WILL BE AROUND
A LONG TIME.
AND NOW COMES TO LONG,
COMPLICATED WORK OF FIGURING OUT
EXACTLY HOW THOSE EVENTS
UNFOLDED AND WHEN.
>> CAN ONLY IMAGINE THE HORROR
THAT THESE PARENTS, THE KIDS,
THEY FELT AS THIS WAS UNFOLDING.
TOM, THANKS VERY MUCH FOR THAT
UPDATE ON WHAT WE KNOW RIGHT
NOW.
MARY SNOW IS IN NEWTOWN FOR US
AS WELL.
I UNDERSTAND YOU JUST SPOKE WITH
A MOTHER AND A CHILD WHO WAS IN
THE SCHOOL DURING THE SHOOTING?
>> Reporter: YES.
WE'RE OUTSIDE A CHURCH WHERE
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN COMING TO COME
AND JUST SAY SOME PRAYERS.
A MOTHER TOOK HER 9-YEAR-OLD
BOY -- HE HEARD GUNSHOTS.
HE HEARD YELLING AND THEN AT ONE
POINT HIS TEACHERS TOLD THE
CHILDREN TO HOLD HANDS AND TO
RUN AS FAST AS THEY COULD AND TO
NOT LOOK INTO THE PRINCIPAL'S
OFFICE AS THEY PASSED.
AND HE SAID HE DID.
THEY RAN OUT OF THE SCHOOL.
AND THEN THEY WERE TAKEN TO A
FIREHOUSE.
AND THAT IS WHERE PARENTS WERE
REUNITED WITH THEIR CHILDREN.
OBVIOUSLY TALKING TO HIM AND HIS
MOTHER, JUST SO STUNNED.
AND THEY'VE COME HERE JUST FOR A
SHORT TIME FOR SOME PEACE.
AND PEOPLE HAVE BEEN FILING IN.
THERE IS GOING TO BE A VIGIL
HERE LATER TONIGHT.
AND OTHERS ARE COMING OUT
TALKING ABOUT STORIES THAT THEY
HAVE HEARD OF TEACHERS REALLY
TRYING TO PROTECT THESE
CHILDREN.
>> MARY, YOU WERE OUTSIDE THE
SUSPECT'S HOUSE, I GUESS, WHERE
THE MOTHER WAS FOUND DEAD
INSIDE.
DESCRIBE WHAT YOU SAW THERE.
>> Reporter: POLICE WERE ON THE
SCENE FOR SEVERAL HOURS AND IT
WAS BLOCKED OFF.
FROM WHERE WE WERE STANDING, I
WAS TOLD BY SOME OF THE
RESIDENTS THAT THE HOUSE WAS
ABOUT A QUARTER OF A MILE IN THE
ROAD.
SO WE COULDN'T GET THAT CLOSE TO
THE HOUSE.
BUT THERE WERE MORE THAN A DOZEN
LAW ENFORCEMENT VEHICLES.
BY THE TIME WE GOT THERE, THE
ROAD WAS BLOCKED OFF.
WE SAW S.W.A.T. TEAMS AT THE
SCENE.
AND THEN IN THE 3:00 HOUR, WE
DID SEE AN AMBULANCE LEAVE THAT
HOUSE.
BUT RESIDENTS WERE EVACUATED.
ONE WOMAN I TALKED TO SAID
POLICE CAME TO HER DOOR AT
AROUND 11:00 IN THE MORNING AND
TOLD HER SHE NEEDED TO LEAVE
RIGHT AWAY.
SH ESCORTED BACK FOR A
SHORT TIME LATER IN THE
AFTERNOON BUT BUZZ THEN TOLD
AGAIN TO GET OUT.
AND AS FAR AS I KNOW, IS STILL
OUT OF THAT HOME.
>> MARY, WE'LL STAY IN CLOSE
TOUCH WITH YOU.
OBVIOUSLY YOU'RE COLLECTING MORE
INFORMATION AS THIS STORY
UNFOLDS.
>> AS MARY WAS RECOUNTING HER
CONVERSATION WITH ONE STUDENT
AND THEIR MOTHER AS THIS ALL
UNFOLDED EARLY THIS MORNING,
LET'S TAKE A LISTEN TO ANOTHER
STUDENT AND HER PARENT AS THEY
OPEN UP ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED.
>> WE SAW POLICE OFFICERS AND WE
HEARD THEM ON THE ROOF AND IN
OUR BUILDING.
>> I WAS PRETTY SHAKEN UP,
DIDN'T KNOW WHO OR WHAT
HAPPENED.
I KNEW THERE WERE SHOOTERS IN
THE BUILDING OR A SHOOTER.
JUST WORRIED ABOUT WHO ELSE WAS
LEFT IN THE BUILDING AT THIS
TIME.
>> IT DOESN'T EVEN SEEM REAL.
IT JUST DOES NOT SEEM LIKE IT'S
EVEN POSSIBLE.
YOU READ IT IN THE PAPER, SEE IT
IN THE NEWS.
YOU'RE LIKE, OH, MY GOD, THAT
POOR FAMILY.
AND THEN YOU HAVE SOMETHING
HAPPEN SO CLOSE TO HOME, IT'S
LIKE, I THINK I'M STILL IN
SHOCK, TO BE HONEST WITH YOU.
>> THE POLICE WERE KNOCKING ON
THE DOOR AND THEY'RE LIKE, WE'RE
EVACUATING PEOPLE, WE'RE
EVACUATING PEOPLE.
SO WE RAN OUT.
THERE WAS POLICE ABOUT AT EVERY
DOOR.
THEY WERE LEADING US DOWN THIS
WAY, DOWN THIS WAY, QUICK,
QUICK, COME ON.
AND WE RAN DOWN TO THE
FIREHOUSE.
THERE WAS A MAN PINNED DOWN TO
THE GROUND WITH HANDCUFFS ON.
AND WE THOUGHT THAT WAS -- WE
DIDN'T GET A GOOD GLANCE AT HIM
BECAUSE THERE WAS A CAR BLOCKING
IT.
PLUS WE WERE RUNNING REALLY
QUICK.
>> IT MAY NOT SEEM REAL BUT YOU
CAN BE SURE THE REALITY OF THIS
TRAGEDY IS SETTING IN FOR SO
MANY FAMILIES THIS EVENING.
CNN WILL BE PROVIDING UPDATES ON
WAYS YOU CAN HELP THE VICTIMS OF
THIS TRAGEDY AND THEIR FAMILIES.
GO TO CNN.COM/IMPACT FOR THE
LATEST INFORMATION ON THAT.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
ANNCR: Some politicians seem to
think Medicare and...
Social Security are just numbers
in a budget.
Well, we worked hard for those
benefits.
We earned them.
And if Washington tries to cram
decisions about the future...
of these programs into a last
minute budget deal...
we'll all pay the price.
AARP is fighting to protect
seniors with responsible...
solutions that strengthen
Medicare and...
Social Security for generations
to come.
We can do better than a last
minute deal...
that would hurt all of us.
CAN YOUR MOISTURIZER DO THAT?
[ Female Announcer ]
DERMATOLOGIST RECOMMENDED
Aveeno HAS AN OAT FORMULA,
NOW PROVEN
TO BUILD A MOISTURE RESERVE,
SO SKIN CAN REPLENISH ITSELF.
THAT'S HEALTHY SKIN FOR LIFE.
ONLY FROM Aveeno.
A REGULAR GUY
WITH AN IRREGULAR HEARTBEAT.
THE USUAL, BOB?
NOT TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
BOB HAS AFIB:
ATRIAL FIBRILLATION NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
A CONDITION THAT PUTS HIM
AT GREATER RISK FOR A STROKE.
[ GPS ] TURN LEFT.
I DON'T THINK SO.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR YEARS, BOB TOOK WARFARIN,
AND MADE A MONTHLY TRIP TO THE
CLINIC TO GET HIS BLOOD TESTED.
BUT NOT ANYMORE.
BOB'S DOCTOR RECOMMENDED
A DIFFERENT OPTION:
ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
XARELTO® IS THE FIRST AND ONLY
ONCE-A-DAY PRESCRIPTION
BLOOD THINNER
FOR PATIENTS WITH AFIB
NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
THAT DOESN'T REQUIRE
ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING.
LIKE WARFARIN,
XARELTO® IS PROVEN EFFECTIVE
TO REDUCE THE RISK
OF AN AFIB-RELATED STROKE.
THERE IS LIMITED DATA
ON HOW THESE DRUGS COMPARE
WHEN WARFARIN IS WELL MANAGED.
NO ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING
MEANS BOB CAN SPEND HIS
EXTRA TIME HOWEVER HE LIKES.
NEW ZEALAND!
XARELTO®
IS JUST ONE PILL A DAY,
TAKEN WITH THE EVENING MEAL.
AND WITH
NO DIETARY RESTRICTIONS,
BOB CAN EAT THE HEALTHY FOODS
HE LIKES.
DO NOT STOP TAKING
XARELTO® RIVAROXABAN
WITHOUT TALKING TO THE DOCTOR
WHO PRESCRIBES IT FOR YOU.
STOPPING MAY INCREASE YOUR RISK
OF HAVING A STROKE.
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU DEVELOP ANY SIGNS
OR SYMPTOMS OF BLEEDING,
LIKE UNUSUAL BRUISING
OR TINGLING.
YOU MAY HAVE A HIGHER RISK
OF BLEEDING
IF YOU TAKE XARELTO®
WITH ASPIRIN PRODUCTS,
NSAIDS OR BLOOD THINNERS.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE TAKING XARELTO®
IF YOU CURRENTLY HAVE
ABNORMAL BLEEDING.
XARELTO® CAN CAUSE BLEEDING,
WHICH CAN BE SERIOUS,
AND RARELY MAY LEAD TO DEATH.
YOU ARE LIKELY TO BRUISE
MORE EASILY ON XARELTO®,
AND IT MAY TAKE LONGER
FOR BLEEDING TO STOP.
TELL YOUR DOCTORS
YOU ARE TAKING XARELTO®
BEFORE ANY PLANNED MEDICAL
OR DENTAL PROCEDURES.
BEFORE STARTING XARELTO®,
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ANY CONDITIONS,
SUCH AS KIDNEY, LIVER
OR BLEEDING PROBLEMS.
READY TO CHANGE YOUR ROUTINE?
ASK YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
FOR MORE INFORMATION
INCLUDING COST SUPPORT OPTIONS,
CALL 1-888-XARELTO
OR VISIT GOXARELTO.COM.
>>> WE JUST TOLD A LITTLE BOY
ABOUT HIS SISTER NOW.
HE SAID, I HAVE NOBODY TO PLAY
WITH NOW.
EXCUSE ME.
>> SO MANY PEOPLE HAVE BEEN
MOVED, UNDERSTANDABLY SO.
I DON'T KNOW HOW PEOPLE CAN COPE
RIGHT NOW.
>> WORDS CANNOT EXPRESS.
YOU CAN JUST SEE THE SORROW ON
EVERYONE'S FACE.
YOU CAN SEE THE PAIN EVEN IN THE
PRESIDENT'S WORDS TODAY.
THIS IS JUST A MOMENT WHEN IT IS
DIFFICULT TO WRAP YOUR MIND
AROUND HOW THIS COULD HAPPEN.
>> THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES HAS TO HOLD BACK TEARS
AND STARTS CRYING SPEAKING TO
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE.
>> IT IS A NATIONAL TRAGEDY.
>> I SPOKE JUST A LITTLE WHILE
AGO WITH A MAN WHOSE 8-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHTER ATTENDS THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY ZOOL.
TELL US WHERE YOU WERE AND WHAT
WAS GOING ON, YOUR CONNECTION TO
THE SCHOOL.
>> MY DAUGHTER'S A THIRD-GRADER.
AND SHE WAS THERE ACTUALLY IN
HER READING CLASS.
THEY HEARD BANGS.
AND THANK GOD FOR MRS. SUMMERS.
HER READING TEACHER GRABBED MY
DAUGHTER AND BROUGHT HER INTO A
BATHROOM AND LOCKED THE DOOR.
ALONG WITH ANOTHER TEACHER.
AND IN A SHORT TIME, SOME POLICE
SOMEHOW WAS ABLE TO GET THEM OUT
OF THERE AND ESCORT THEM THROUGH
THE HALLWAY.
UNFORTUNATELY IT WAS A PRETTY
MESSY SCENE FOR MY DAUGHTER.
>> EARLIER IN THE DAY, I SPOKE
WITH YOUR WIFE, LISA.
SHE SAYS YOUR DAUGHTER SEEMS TO
BE OKAY.
YOU ALSO HAVE A 10-YEAR-OLD SON.
HOW ARE THE KIDS DOING NOW IS?
>> I DON'T KNOW IF MY DAUGHTER
IS IN SHOCK OR WHAT.
SHE'S DOING INCREDIBLY WELL.
MY SON IS DOING GREAT, TOO.
BUT THERE ARE A LOT OF FEARS
THAT THIS KIND OF THING --
EVERYTHING -- THE GAME'S CHANGED
FROM THIS POINT ONWARD.
>> WHAT DOES THAT MEAN WHEN YOU
SAY THE GAME HAS CHANGED --
>> I MEAN, MY KIDS ARE ALREADY
ASKING WHEN'S THIS GOING TO
HAPPEN AGAIN?
IT WAS ONLY A WEEK AGO THAT WE
WERE TALKING ABOUT THIS TYPE OF
SITUATION AND I SAID, THE
CHANCES OF IT HAPPENING ARE ONE
IN A ZILLION AT SANDY HOOK.
AND I WAS WRONG ABOUT THAT.
>> WE KNOW, DECLAN, YOU KNEW THE
PRINCIPAL WELL.
SHE WAS KILLED IN THIS MASS
MURDER TODAY.
TELL US A LITTLE BIT ABOUT HER.
>> SHE JUST -- SHE WAS JUST SO
NICE AND SHE LOVED HER JOB.
AND SHE ACTUALLY ON A COUPLE OF
OCCASIONS WENT OUT OF HER WAY
JUST TO HELP US WITH CERTAIN
THINGS THAT WE WERE WORKING ON
WITH OUR DAUGHTER.
THIS IS ALL SO SURREAL.
SO PLEASE FORGIVE ME IF I'M A
LITTLE CLOUDY RIGHT NOW.
>> NO, BELIEVE ME, WE APPRECIATE
WHAT YOU'RE GOING THROUGH.
WE CAN'T EVEN IMAGINE WHAT
YOU'RE GOING THROUGH.
JOHN KING IS WITH US AS WELL.
HE'S GOT A QUESTION.
>> SIR, SADLY IN ANY COMMUNITY
WHEN TRAGEDY LIKE THIS HAPPENS,
THERE ARE ALWAYS QUESTIONS ABOUT
THE NOTIFICATION SYSTEM.
HOW DID YOU FIRST LEARN?
HOW SPECIFIC WAS THAT
INFORMATION AND OBVIOUSLY THE
OFFICIALS AT THE SCHOOL WERE
DEALING WITH A TRAGEDY ON THE
SCENE?
BUT DO YOU THINK THAT PART OF IT
WAS HANDLED APPROPRIATELY?
>> I THINK IT'S THE BEST THEY
COULD DO.
I DON'T KNOW HOW YOU REALLY
PREPARE FOR SOMETHING THIS
CRAZY.
MY WIFE CALLED ME.
I WORK DOWN IN NEW YORK AND MY
WIFE CALLED ME AND TOLD ME THERE
HAD BEEN A SHOOTING AND SO I
RUSHED HOME.
MY WIFE WAS ALREADY IN TOWN AND
SHE RAN THERE.
BUT SO FAR, THE NEWTOWN SCHOOL
SYSTEM HAS BEEN GREAT IN LEAVING
AUTOMATIC PHONE UPDATES WITH ALL
THE PARENTS.
>> SAD STORY.
QUICK QUESTION BEFORE I LET YOU
GO, DECLAN.
AT SOME POINT YOU'RE GOING TO
HAVE TO MAKE A DECISION ABOUT
LETTING YOUR KIDS GO BACK TO THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO?
>> WELL, I MEAN, THIS IS ALL SO
NEW.
I'VE BEEN TALKING TO MY KIDS AND
EXPLAINING, LOOK, THIS IS WHAT
HAPPEN
HAPPENED.
YOU DO YOUR BEST TO COMMUNICATE
WITH THEM AND YOU DO YOUR BEST
TO -- IT'S FUNNY, A BOMB HIT,
THERE'S A LOT OF SMOKE AND IT'S
STILL HERE.
I HAVEN'T HAD MY -- ENOUGH TIME
TO REALLY PLAN.
BUT HOPEFULLY BY THE TIME THEY
DO GO BACK TO SCHOOL, I'LL HAVE
DONE A GOOD ENOUGH JOB OF
TALKING TO MY KIDS AND MAKING
THEM FEEL AT LEAST THE MOST
COMFORTABLE THEY COULD.
>> HOW'S YOUR WIFE, LISA, DOING?
>> WELL, SHE'S HANGING IN THERE.
>> PLEASE GIVE ALL OF THEM OUR
LOVE, OUR SYMPATHY, OUR SUPPORT.
AND WE WISH THEM ONLY THE BEST,
DECLAN.
A PARENT OF TWO KIDS FROM THAT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE'RE FOLLOWING THE BREAKING
NEWS HERE IN "THE SITUATION
ROOM."
ONE OF THE WORST SCHOOL
SHOOTINGS IN AMERICAN HISTORY,
EVEN MORE HORRIFIC BECAUSE THE
CARNAGE WAS AT AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW RIGHT NOW.
POLICE SAY A GUNMAN KILLED 20
CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS AT THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
THE SMALL CONNECTICUT TOWN OF
NEWTOWN.
THESE WERE YOUNG KIDS, INCLUDING
KYNAINDERGARTENER
KINDERGARTENERS.
TERRIFIED CHILDREN WERE LED OUT
OF THE SCHOOL AFTER THE SHOOTING
THIS MORNING HOLDING ONTO ONE
ANOTHER.
PARENTS RUSHED TO THE SCENE TO
FIND OUT IF THEIR CHILDREN WERE
DEAD OR ALIVE.
>> THESE PARENTS WERE WAITING
FOR THEIR CHILDREN TO COME OUT.
THEY THOUGHT THAT THEY WERE
STILL ALIVE.
THERE'S 20 PARENTS THAT WERE
JUST TOLD THAT THEIR CHILDREN
ARE DEAD.
IT WAS AWFUL.
>> POLICE HAVE NOT IDENTIFIED
THE GUNMAN BUT THEY SAY HE DID
DIE AT THE SCENE, APPARENTLY
KILLING HIMSELF.
WE ARE TOLD THE MOTHER OF THE
SUSPECTED SHOOTER HAS BEEN FOUND
DEAD AT HER SON'S HOME IN
NEWTOWN.
AN EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT OBAMA
WIPED AWAY TEARS AS HE OFFERED
SUPPORT AND PRAYERS FOR THE
FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS OF THE
SCHOOL TRAGEDY.
>> THIS AFTERNOON, I SPOKE WITH
GOVERNOR MALLOY AND FBI DIRECTOR
MUELLER.
I OFFERED GOVERNOR MALLOY MY
CONDOLENCES ON BEHALF OF THE
NATION AND MADE IT CLEAR HE WILL
HAVE EVERY SINGLE RESOURCE THAT
HE NEEDS TO INVESTIGATE THIS
HEINOUS CRIME, CARE FOR THE
VICTIMS, COUNSEL THEIR FAMILIES.
WE'VE ENDURED TOO MANY OF THESE
TRAGEDIES IN THE PAST FEW YEARS.
AND EACH TIME I LEARN THE NEWS,
I REACT NOT AS A PRESIDENT BUT
AS ANYBODY ELSE WOULD, AS A
PARENT.
AND THAT WAS ESPECIALLY TRUE
TODAY.
I KNOW THERE'S NOT A PARENT IN
AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN, BEAUTIFUL
LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN THE AGES OF
5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM, BIRTHDAYS,
GRADUATIONS, WEDDINGS, KIDS OF
THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS, MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES TO HELPING
OUR CHILDREN FULFILL THEIR
DREAMS.
SO OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN
THOUSAND DOLLAR FOR THE PARENTS
AND GRANDPARENTS, SISTERS AND
BROTHERS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN AND FOR THE FAMILIES OF
THE ADULTS WHO WERE LOST.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN FOR THE
PARENTS OF THE SURVIVORS AS
WELL.
FOR AS BLESSED AS THEY ARE TO
HAVE THEIR CHILDREN HOME
TONIGHT, THEY KNOW THAT THEIR
CHILDREN'S INNOCENCE HAS BEEN
TORN AWAY FROM THEM TOO EARLY
AND THERE ARE NO WORDS THAT WILL
EASE THEIR PAIN.
AS A COUNTRY, WE HAVE BEEN
THROUGH THIS TOO MANY TIMES,
WHETHER IT'S AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN OR A SHOPPING
MALL IN OREGON OR A TEMPLE IN
WISCONSIN OR A MOVIE THEATER IN
AURORA OR A STREET CORNER IN
CHICAGO, THESE NEIGHBORHOODS ARE
OUR NEIGHBORHOODS AND THESE
CHILDREN ARE OUR CHILDREN.
AND WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO COME
TOGETHER AND TAKE MEANINGFUL
ACTION TO PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS, REGARDLESS OF THE
POLITICS.
THIS EVENING, MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT
IN AMERICA WILL DO, WHICH IS HUG
OUR CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER
AND WE'LL TELL THEM THAT WE LOVE
THEM AND WE'LL REMIND EACH OTHER
HOW DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT.
AND THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT
NOW IN THE HARD DAYS TO COME.
THAT COMMUNITY NEEDS US TO BE AT
OUR BEST AS AMERICANS AND I WILL
EVERYTHING IN MY POWER AS
PRESIDENT TO HELP.
BECAUSE WHILE NOTHING CAN FILL
THE SPACE OF A LOST CHILD OR
LOVED ONE, ALL OF US CAN EXTEND
A HAND TO THOSE IN NEED TO
REMIND THEM THAT WE ARE THERE
FOR THEM, THAT WE ARE PRAYING
FOR THEM, THAT THE LOVE THEY
FELT FOR THOSE THEY LOST ENDURES
NOT JUST IN THEIR MEMORIES BUT
ALSO IN OURS.
MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF THE
VICTIMS AND IN THE WORDS OF SP
RISHGSCZER, HEAL THE BROKEN
HEARTED AND BIND UP THEIR
WOUNDS.
>> YOU SEE A LIVE PICTURE OF THE
WHITE HOUSE FLAG FLYING AT HALF
STAFF.
IT'S NOT OFTEN IF EVER YOU SEE A
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
BREAK DOWN LIKE THAT.
>> ABSOLUTELY NOT.
HE'S KNOWN TO BE VERY STOIC EVEN
GOING AS FAR AS SAYING HE CAN
COME OFF AS STANDOFFISH.
BUT NOT THE CASE TODAY.
HE SAID, OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN
TODAY.
I THINK EVERYONE WATCHING HOW
THIS IS UNFOLDED THROUGHOUT THE
DAY -- ALL ASKING THE SAME
QUESTION, HOW DID THIS HAPPEN,
WHY DID THIS HAPPEN?
AND EVERYONE'S SEARCHING FOR IF
THERE ARE ANY KIND OF WORDS THAT
COULD BE SAID TO TRY TO HELP
THESE FAMILIES BEGIN TO HEAL.
WE ALL KNOW THAT THOG CAN FILL
THAT VOID RIGHT NOW.
>> HE BREAK DOWN THE FIRST TIME
WHEN HE SAID THESE KIDS WERE 5
YEARS OLD TO 10 YEARS OLD AND HE
SPOKE AS A PARENT.
HE'S GOT TWO GIRLS HE SENDS TO
SCHOOL EVERY DAY.
YOU ASSUME THEY'RE SAFE AND
SECURE AND THEY'RE GOING TO COME
HOME EVERY DAY.
AND WHAT HAPPENS LIKE THIS?
ALL OF A SUDDEN, BOOM, IT'S SUCH
A SHOCK.
DR. DREW PINSKY IS JOINING US
FOR A LITTLE ANALYSIS.
DR. DREW, YOU SEE THE PRESIDENT
BREAKING DOWN.
PEOPLE ARE BREAKING DOWN ALL
OVER THE COUNTRY RIGHT NOW JUST
LISTENING TO THE PRESIDENT.
>> WOLF, THAT'S ABSOLUTELY
RIGHT.
ONE OF THE MOST IMPORTANT THINGS
HE DID THERE WAS TO SHOW US,
REFLECT FOR US FEELINGS THAT WE
ARE ALL FEELING.
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT YOU, EVERY
FIVE MINUTES, I'M SORT OF TAKEN
OVER BY A WAVE OF A DIFFERENT
FEELING.
I'VE GONE FROM HEARTBREAK LIKE
HE MENTIONED.
THEN I GO TO ANGER AND RAGE AND
DISGUST.
TEN MINUTES AGO, I WAS FEELING
NUMB AND FATIGUED AND DEPLETED.
NOW I'M BACK TO DISGUSTED AGAIN.
I'VE COMPLETELY, COMPLETELY
DISGUSTED THAT WE ARE HERE
HAVING THIS CONVERSATION ABOUT
YET AGAIN ANOTHER UNBELIEVABLY
SENSELESS ACT.
THERE IS NO REASON FOR THIS.
BUT I WILL TELL YOU THIS.
ONE OF THE THINGS THE PRESIDENT
DID SAY IS THAT WE NEED TO SAY
OUR PRAYERS FOR THE FAMILIES
THAT HAVE LOST SOMEONE IN
CONNECTICUT WHICH CATEGORICALLY
WE DO.
BUT I'LL TELL YOU WHAT, EACH AND
EVERY ONE OF US HAVE TO PAY
ATTENTION TO OUR CHILDREN IN OUR
FAMILIES TONIGHT BECAUSE EVERY
FAMILY IN AMERICA IS AFFECTED BY
THIS EVENT.
THAT AMAZING INTERVIEW YOU
PLAYED A FEW MOMENTS AGO FROM
DECLAN, THE FATHER OF A YOUNG
ONE AT THE SCHOOL, HIS CHILDREN
WERE ASKING HIM, DADDY, WHEN IS
THIS GOING TO HAPPEN AGAIN?
THAT'S THE WORLD WE LIVE IN,
WOLF, WHERE SOME PEOPLE ARE
BEING PUSHED IN FRONT OF
SUBWAYS.
PEOPLE ARE NOT SAFE IN THE MALL.
THEY'RE NOT SAFE IN THEIR
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WHEN IS THIS GOING TO HAPPEN
AGAIN?
IT'S INCUMBENT UPON US, OUR
HOUSEHOLDS, OUR COMMUNITIES, TO
MAKE SURE NOW IT NEVER HAPPENS
AGAIN.
>> DR. DREW, HOW DO YOU BEGIN --
WHAT IS YOUR ADVICE TO PARENTS
AS THEY'RE WATCHING THIS?
KIDS ARE VERY PERCEPTIVE AND CAN
PICK UP SIGNALS FROM THEIR
PARENTS AND CAN SEE ALL THIS
UNFOLDING ON THE TELEVISION IF
THEY'RE WATCHING IT.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> WHAT IS YOUR ADVICE TO
PARENTS AND HOW THEY BEGIN TO
EXPLAIN THIS TO CHILDREN?
BECAUSE IT'S IMPOSSIBLE FOR EVEN
US AS ADULTS TO TRY TO BEGIN TO
WRAP OUR MINDS AROUND SOMETHING
LIKE THIS.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
IT'S IMPORTANT TO HELP THEM TO
TRY TOP IDENTITY THEIR FEELINGS,
TO REFLECT BACK TO THEM, THAT
IT'S APPROPRIATE TO BE SCARED,
THAT IT'S REASONABLE TO BE
CONFUSED, THAT THIS IS
SENSELESS.
BUT IT'S REALLY OUR JOB TO LEAD
OUR FAMILIES OUT OF THIS AND
MAKE THEM FEEL SECURE.
THINK ABOUT OUR FAMILY SYSTEMS
IN THIS COUNTRY TODAY.
NOT EVERY CHILD FEELS SECURE AND
SAFE IN THEIR FAMILY.
AND IT IS INCUMBENT UPON THE BIG
PEOPLE TO TAKE CARE OF THE
LITTLE PEOPLE SO THAT HORRIBLE
THINGS LIKE THIS DON'T HAPPEN
WHEN THEY GROW UP.
SO REALLY IT'S DOUBLE DOWN, MAKE
YOUR KIDS FEEL SAFE.
ALLOW THEM TO EXPRESS THEIR
FEELINGS BUT LET THEM KNOW THAT
YOU WILL BE SURE THAT THEY GROW
UP AND FLOURISH BECAUSE THAT IS
YOUR JOB.
>> AND ONE QUICK FINAL QUESTION,
DR. DREW, A LITTLE CHILD SEES
MOMMY OR DADDY CRYING RIGHT NOW.
THEY SAY, MOMMY, DADDY, WHY ARE
YOU CRYING?
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
>> YOU SAY, IT'S GOOD.
I'M HAVING FEELINGS ABOUT THESE
POOR PEOPLE THAT HAVE LOST
SOMETHING.
I'M HAVING A FEELING.
DON'T WORRY.
IT'S NOT BECAUSE OF YOU.
CHILDREN WILL FEEL THAT
EVERYTHING THAT HAPPENS IN HAIR
LIFE IS BECAUSE OF THEM AND
EVERYTHING THAT HAS HAPPENED IN
THE WORLD IS GOING TO HAPPEN TO
THEM.
SO THEY FEEL VULNERABLE BECAUSE
OTHER KIDS HAVE BEEN HURT AND
THEY'RE GOING TO FEEL OUT OF
CONTROL WHEN THEY SEE YOU BE
EMOTIONAL.
BUT JUST EXPRESS IT.
I THINK THE PRESIDENT DID A
WONDERFUL JOB TODAY OF REALLY
MODELING THAT SORT OF BEHAVIOR
FOR EACH AND EVERY ONE OF US.
BUT IT'S ALSO IMPORTANT FOR US
TO HEAR FROM OUR LEADERS THAT
IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
THE GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT SAID
CONNECTICUT WILL GET THROUGH.
THOSE ARE MORE THE REASSURING
WORDS THAT WE ALL HAVE TO HEAR
SO WE CAN EACH INDIVIDUAL LEAD
OUR COMMUNITIES, LEAD OUR
HOUSEHOLDS.
>> DR. DREW PINSKY FROM OUR
SISTER NETWORK, HLN.
DR. DREW, THANKS VERY MUCH.
POWERFUL, VERY IMPORTANT WORDS.
LET'S TAKE ANOTHER QUICK BREAK,
RESUME OUR SPECIAL COVERAGE OF
THIS HORRIFIC TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT RIGHT AFTER THIS.
Capella University understands
businesses are trying to come
back from rough economic times.
Employees are being forced to do
more with less.
And the need for capable leaders
is greater than ever.
When you see these problems do
you take a step back,
or do you want to dive right in?
With a degree in business from
Capella University, you'll have
the knowledge to go further in
your career than you ever
thought possible.
Let's get started at CAPELLA.EDU
>>> SUSAN CANDIOTTI IS ON THE
SCENE FOR US IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
SUSAN, I UNDERSTAND YOU'RE
GETTING NEW INFORMATION ABOUT
THE SHOOTER.
>> Reporter: THAT'S RIGHT.
AND CONTRARY TO CONFLICTING
INFORMATION THAT INVESTIGATORS
THEMSELVES HAD EARLIER AND HAD
PASSED ON, WE CAN NOW TELL YOU
ACCORDING TO SEVERAL SOURCES
THAT THE NAME OF THE SHOOTER IN
THIS CASE IS ADAM LANZA.
HE IS 20 YEARS OLD AND HIS
BROTHER'S NAME IS RYAN LANZA.
IT IS ADAM LANZA, 20 YEARS OLD,
WHO IS THE SHOOTER.
HIS BROTHER, RYAN, IS THE ONE
THAT WAS TAKEN AWAY FOR
QUESTIONING BY AUTHORITIES IN
HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY, AND IS
EXPECTED THAT HE WILL BE
RELEASED.
HE IS NOT CONSIDERED A SUSPECT.
WE DON'T KNOW WHEN HE WILL BE
RELEASED.
WE ALSO HAVE THIS ADDITIONAL
INFORMATION THAT THE FATHER OF
THE SHOOTER.
THERE IS NO INDICATION THAT THE
BROTH
FATHER IS A SUSPECT IN THIS
CASE.
HE IS DIVORCED FROM NANCY LANZA,
IDENTIFIED AS A VICTIM IN THIS
CASE.
HE REMARRIED AND LIVES IN THE
SAME AREA WHERE THIS SHOOTING
OCCURRED.
SO THAT IS THE NEW INFORMATION
THAT WE HAVE ABOUT NOW.
WE HAVE THE NAME OF THE SHOOTER
AS ADAM LANZA, 20 YEARS OLD.
HIS OLDER BROTHER, RYAN, 24
YEARS OLD, IS THE ONE WHO WAS
QUESTIONED IN HOBOKEN, NEW
JERSEY.
HE IS EXPECTED TO BE RELEASED.
WE DON'T KNOW WHEN.
THE FATHER OF BOTH OF THEM ALSO
QUESTIONED FOR INFORMATION ABOUT
THE SHOOTER IN THIS CASE, HIS
SON.
BUT THERE IS NO INDICATION THAT
THE FATHER IS CONSIDERED A
SUSPECT IN ANY WAY.
WOLF?
>> JUST TO RECAP, THE VIDEO THAT
WE SAW OF SOMEBODY BEING TAKEN
AWAY, THIS IS RYAN LANZA, THERE
IT IS, COURTESY OF OUR AFFILIATE
WCBS IN NEW YORK.
THAT IS LINE LANZA.
I BELIEVE HE'S 24 YEARS OLD.
HE'S THE OLDER BROTHER OF THE
MAN NOW SUSPECTED OF BEING THE
SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA WHO'S 20
YEARS OLD.
THERE YOU SEE THE POLICE OFFICER
TAKING RYAN LANZA AWAY.
THEIR MOTHER, NANCY LANZA, WAS
FOUND DEAD IN THE HOUSE IN
NEWTOWN.
THAT'S RIGHT, SUSAN?
>> Reporter: THAT'S RIGHT.
THAT IS CORRECT.
SHE WAS FOUND DEAD AT THAT
RESIDENCE HERE IN NEWTOWN.
AND WE ARE STILL WAITING FOR ALL
OF THESE NAMES TO BE OFFICIALLY
RELEASED BY AUTHORITIES.
THEY HAVEN'T DONE SO YET.
BUT WE'VE BEEN ABLE TO CONFIRM
THIS THROUGH SEVERAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT SOURCES.
>> AND THE PARENTS ARE DIVORCED
AND SO THE FATHER LIVES
ELSEWHERE.
AND THERE'S NO INDICATION HE HAD
ANY KNOWLEDGE OF ANYTHING ALONG
THESE LINES, IS THAT RIGHT?
>> Reporter: THERE'S NO
INDICATION OF THAT AT ALL, NO
INDICATION OF THAT AT ALL, WOLF.
>> SUSAN, THANKS FOR CLARIFYING
THAT.
I SUSPECT THOSE MICROPHONES
BEHIND YOU WILL BE USED FAIRLY
SOON, THE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE, LOCAL LAW ENFORCEMENT, I
ASSUME, WILL BE COMING TO BRIEF
THE NEWS MEDIA ON SPECIFIC
INFORMATION.
BUT THERE YOU HAVE IT, KATE.
THE LATEST INFORMATION FROM
SUSAN CANDIOTTI.
>> DOING GREAT REPORTING FOR US.
LET'S GO TO PRODUCER ADAM REESE.
HE'S ON THE GROUND IN HOBOKEN,
NEW JERS.
HE'S ON THE PHONE WITH US.
ADAM, WE WERE JUST SEEING VIDEO
FROM OUR AFFILIATE, WCBS OF THE
SUSPECTED SHOOTER'S BROTHER.
WE'RE LOOKING AT IT AGAIN HERE.
THIS IS THE BROTHER OF THE
SUSPECTED SHOOTER, THIS MAN'S
NAME THAT YOU'RE SEEING IN THIS
VIDEO IS RYAN LANZA, WE ARE
TOLD.
AND THE SHOOTER, AS SUSAN
CANDIOTTI, IS LEARNING FROM
SOURCES, IS ADAM LANZA.
WHAT MORE ARE YOU LEARNING ON
THE GROUND IN HOBOKEN THIS
EVENING?
>> Reporter: WELL, THE POLICE
HERE HAVE JUST OPENED UP THE
STREETS OUTSIDE HIS APARTMENT,
1313 GRAND, THE NAME OF THE
BUILDING IS CALLED THE
METROPOLITAN.
THE POLICE HAVE JUST DROPPED THE
POLICE TAPE, OPENED UP THE
STREETS THERE ARE STILL SEVERAL
OFFICES AND AN FBI AGENT IN
FRONT OF THE BUILDING MAKING
SURE ONLY RESIDENTS GO INTO THE
BUILDING.
AS YOU JUST REPORTED, THE
SHOOTER'S BROTHER, RYAN LANZA
WAS TAKEN FROM THIS APARTMENT
BUILDING EARLIER TODAY IN
HANDCUFFS.
HE LOOKED A LITTLE BIT DAZED
BASED ON THE VIDEO WE SAW.
THE BUILDING IS A FIVE-STORY
BUILDING, ONE, TWO AND
THREE-BEDROOM APARTMENTS.
IT'S A RESIDENTIAL NEIGHBORHOOD.
HOBOKEN IS A GROWING COMMUNITY
OF PROFESSIONALS.
IT'S RIGHT ON THE WATER FACING
MANHATTAN.
IN ADDITION TO RYAN LANZA, TWO
ROOMMATES WERE TAKEN INTO
CUSTODY.
THEY WERE TAKEN IN FOR
QUESTIONING BUT THEY ARE NOT
BELIEVED TO BE ASSOCIATED WITH
THE SHOOTING, AT LEAST ACCORDING
TO THE POLICE CHIEF WHO BRIEFED
THE MEDIA HERE EARLIER TODAY.
SO THERE'S STILL PLENTY OF
MEDIA.
BUT I CAN SAY THIS SCENE HERE
HAS DIED DOWN QUITE A BIT.
>> ADAM, YOU SAID THE
AUTHORITIES SEEM TO BE OPENING
UP THE STREET NEAR THIS
APARTMENT BUILDING WHERE RYAN
LANZA LIVES.
WE MUST TAKE THAT AS AN
INDICATION THAT THEY DON'T THINK
THERE'S ANY MORE INVESTIGATION
THAT NEEDS TO OCCUR THERE WHICH
WORKS WITH THE REPORTING FROM
SUSAN CANDIOTTI THAT HER SOURCES
SAY THAT SHE BELIEVES THAT RYAN
LANZA WILL BE RELEASED FROM
POLICE CUSTODY AT SOME POINT,
SHE JUST DOESN'T KNOW WHEN.
>> Reporter: THAT'S MY
UNDERSTANDING AS WELL.
THAT HE WILL BE RELEASED AT SOME
POINT, THAT HE IS BEING
QUESTIONED AND APPARENTLY WE ARE
TOLD HE IS BEING COOPERATIVE.
AND WE ARE WAITING FOR HIS
RETURN HERE AT THE APARTMENT
BUILDING.
>> ADAM, MANY THREADS TO FOLLOW
IN THIS STILL-DEVELOPING STORY
AND THIS TRAGEDY AS WE'RE
WATCHING.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> JOE JOHNS IS HERE, OUR CRIME
AND JUSTICE CORRESPONDENT.
YOU'RE GETTING MORE INFORMATION
ON THE WEAPON OR WEAPONS THAT
WERE USED TODAY?
>> RIGHT.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT THREE
DIFFERENT GUNS HERE, A GLOCK, A
SIG SAUER AND A BUSHMASTER .223.
THAT WAS THE KIND OF WEAPON THAT
WAS USED IN THE BELTWAY SNIPER
SHOOTINGS YEARS AND YEARS AGO.
AN ASSAULT WEAPON.
IT TURNS OUT, ACCORDING TO LAW
ENFORCEMENT SOURCES, WHO HAVE
TALKED TO OUR CAROL KRADDY, THAT
ALL THREE OF THESE WEAPONS WERE
REGISTERED TO THE MOTHER OF THE
SHOOTER.
>> NANCY LANZA.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE DON'T KNOW ANYTHING MORE
ABOUT THAT.
WE DO KNOW THAT THE BUREAU OF
ALCOHOL, TOBACCO AND FIREARMS
DOES LOTS AND LOTS OF TRACING OF
THESE WEAPONS WHENEVER YOU HAVE
A SITUATION LIKE THIS.
THEY BELIEVE THAT THEY'RE GOING
TO GO THROUGH ALL THEIR TRAPS.
BUT BOTTOM LINE IS, THESE
WEAPONS WERE APPARENTLY
PURCHASED LEGALLY BY NANCY
LANZA, NOT BY THE SHOOTER, ADAM.
AND THAT APPARENTLY IS THE END
OF THE INVESTIGATION.
>> ADAM LANZA IS DEAD,
APPARENTLY TOOK HIS OWN LIFE,
THE 20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER.
NANCY LANZA IS DEAD, SHE WAS
KILLED AT PRESUMABLY AT THE
HOUSE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THIS INFORMATION, CAROL, I'M
GETTING INFORMATION FROM HER AS
WELL, THESE ARE RECORDS THAT
COME IN FROM THE CONNECTICUT
FIREARMS REGISTRATION SYSTEM
WHICH IS A PRETTY SOPHISTICATED
GUN CONTROL OPERATION IN
CONNECTICUT.
>> YEAH, IT'S A COMPLICATED
TRACE THAT THE ATF HAS TO GO
THROUGH.
THEY HAVE TO GO TO THE
MANUFACTURER, THEN THEY HAVE TO
GO TO THE FIRST DISTRIBUTOR,
THEN THEY HAVE TO GO TO THE
FIRST PURCHASER.
AND IF THERE'S ANOTHER
PURCHASER, THEN THEY HAVE TO
FOLLOW THE CHAIN ALL THE WAY
THROUGH.
THAT'S THE WAY THE LAW WORKS.
BUT A LOT OF TIMES IN THESE BIG
CASES, THEY'RE ABLE TO LOOK AT
THE SITUATION, FIND OUT WHO
OWNED THE GUNS, WHO PURCHASED
THE GUNS, VERY QUICKLY.
APPARENTLY THE AUTHORITIES HAVE
BEEN ABLE TO RUN THOSE TRAPS.
>> WHICH SHE'S ALSO SUGGESTING,
THE GLOCK AND THE SIG SAUER
HANDGUNS WERE FOUND INSIDE THE
SCHOOL.
>> RIGHT.
AND THE BUSHMASTER OUTSIDE.
>> FOUND IN THE CAR.
OBVIOUSLY THAT WAS NOT USED.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> AT LEAST NOT IN KILLING THESE
KIDS, THE TEACHERS, THE
PRINCIPAL.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
THE QUESTION IS, AT LEAST ONE OF
THE MANY QUESTIONS WE'VE BEEN
ASKING THE AUTHORITIES AND
HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE TO GET TO YET,
IS WHETHER THE MAGAZINES ON
THOSE WEAPONS WERE -- THE LARGE,
EXTENDED MAGAZINES OR WHETHER
THEY WERE THE MAGAZINES THAT
TYPICALLY COME WITH THE
FIREARMS.
THAT WILL BE INTERESTING.
BECAUSE THAT'S ALL PART OF THE
GUN CONTROL DEBATE, WHETHER
THOSE MAGAZINES ARE APPROPRIATE
FOR PEOPLE TO HAVE JUST ON THE
STREETS.
>> WE SAW THE PICTURES OF THOSE
GUNS.
OBVIOUSLY THEY KILLED A LOT OF
PEOPLE.
>> NOW I THINK -- LET'S TAKE YOU
TO SOME LIVE PICTURES I BELIEVE
THAT WE HAVE.
IT'S ST. ST. ROSE OF LIMA ROMAN
CATHOLIC CHURCH.
THIS IS WHERE WE'RE SPEAKING TO
A COUPLE OF OUR CORRESPONDENTS.
THIS IS WHERE A VIGIL WILL BE
TAKING PLACE STARTING ANY MINUTE
NOW.
THIS IS IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
ACCORDING TO CORRESPONDENTS ON
THE GROUND THIS HAS BEEN A SITE
WHERE MANY PEOPLE IN THE
COMMUNITY HAVE COME TO JUST SEEK
SOME QUIET, SEEK SOME SOLACE,
AND JASON CARROLL ROLL, OUR
CORRESPONDENT WHO'S BEEN ON THE
GROUND, SPOKE WITH THE DEACON
THERE EARLIER TODAY AND EVEN THE
DEACON FOUND IT VERY HARD TO
FIND -- HE WAS EVEN LOST FOR
WORDS, TRYING TO FIGURE OUT HOW
TO PROVIDE THE KIND OF SUPPORT
AND LOVE TO THE MANY
PARISHIONERS WHO WILL BE COMING
THERE OBVIOUSLY FOR THIS VIG
JIT.
I THINK WE SEE CARS STREAMING
IN, IT COULD BE STARTING ANY
MINUTE NOW, YOU KNOW WE'LL HAVE
MUCH MORE LIVE COVERAGE OF THAT
AS WE'LL BE WATCHING THIS
UNFOLD.
>> WHAT CAN YOU SAY, A STORY
LIKE THIS.
>> NOTHING YOU CAN SAY.
>> IT'S OBVIOUSLY A HORRIFIC,
HORRIFIC TRAGEDY.
ALL OF US, EVERYONE IN THE
COUNTRY, EVERYONE IN THE WORLD
MIGHT BE WATCHING RIGHT NOW, CAN
RELATE.
YOU SEND A KID TO SCHOOL,
SOMEBODY IN KINDERGARTEN, A
FIRST GRADE, SECOND GRADE, THIRD
GRADE.
JOE, YOU'RE HERE.
JUST SO SAD TO THINK ABOUT IT.
LET'S TAKE A QUICK BREAK, RESUME
OUR COVERAGE RIGHT AFTER THIS.
AND WE CAN SAVE YOU
10% ON GROUND SHIPPING
OVER THE UPS STORE.
LOOK THIS ISN'T
MY FIRST CHRISTMAS.
THESE DEALS ALL SEEM GREAT
AT THE TIME...
BUT LATER...
[ shirt ]
MERRY CHRISTMAS, EVERYBODY!
NOT SO MUCH.
HO HO HO!
THIS ISN'T
THAT KIND OF DEAL.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SAVE ON GROUND SHIPPING
AT FEDEX OFFICE.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN DIARRHEA HITS,
KAOPECTATE STOPS IT FAST.
POWERFUL LIQUID RELIEF
SPEEDS TO THE SOURCE.
FAST.
[ Male Announcer ]
STOP THE UH-OH FAST
WITH KAOPECTATE.
>>> THESE ARE LIVE PICTURES OF
THE ST. ROSE OF LIMA ROMAN
CATHOLIC CHURCH IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
A VIGIL IS ABOUT TO BEGIN RIGHT
THERE.
JUST A FEW MOMENTS AGO WE DID
GET SOME REACTION FROM SOMEONE
WHO KNEW ADAM LANZA, THE
SUSPECTED SHOOTER IN THIS CASE,
THE 20-YEAR-OLD WHO WENT INTO
THAT SCHOOL AND OPENED FIRE.
>> JUST A KID.
>> Reporter: JUST A KID?
NEVER ANTI-SOCIAL?
>> NO.
ADAM'S GOT A -- NO.
>> Reporter: TROUBLEMAKER?
>> NO, DEFINITELY NOT.
>> Reporter: NOTICEABLE?
DID HE JUST KIND OF BLEND INTO
THE BACKGROUND?
>> YEAH.
NOTHING -- NOTHING THAT WOULD
WARRANT ANY OF THIS.
>> Reporter: THEY'RE SAYING HE
WENT AFTER HIS MOM AND HER CLASS
OF KIDS.
CAN YOU WRAP YOUR HEAD AROUND
THAT?
>> NO, I CANNOT.
I DON'T KNOW WHO WOULD DO
ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
>> Reporter: SO YOUR GENERAL
SENSE IS WHAT?
>> THIS IS -- THIS IS
UNSPEAKABLE.
I FIRST HEARD ABOUT IT -- I'M
STILL IN SHOCK.
JUST GIVE ME A MOMENT, I WANT TO
GO.
I'VE GOT TO GO.
>> VERY DIFFICULT TIME FOR SO
MANY PEOPLE.
>> YEAH.
THAT'S SOME CLASSMATE OF ADAM
LANZA, THE 20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER
IN THIS CASE, SPEAKING OUT,
SAYING HE'S JUST AN AVERAGE KID.
>> AVERAGE KID.
WE'VE HEARD THAT SO MANY TIMES.
>> WE ALWAYS HEAR THAT.
>> YOU ALWAYS HEAR THAT, EVERY
TIME.
>> SHOCKED BY WHAT'S GOING ON.
>>> THE PRESIDENT, THE FIRST
LADY, AND MANY PEOPLE ALL ACROSS
THE COUNTRY MAY BE HAVING SOME
HEARTFELT AND DIFFICULT
CONVERSATIONS WITH THEIR KIDS
TONIGHT.
YOU CAN BE SURE OF THAT IN THE
WAKE OF THE HORRIFIC CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL MASSACRE.
LEASE SA SYLVESTER HAS MORE ON
THIS.
>> Reporter: IF THERE'S AN IMAGE
THAT SUMS UP THIS STORY, IT IS
THIS.
ANY PARENT OUT THERE CAN RELATE.
PSYCHIATRIST CHARLES RAISEN IS
IN THE UNIVERSITY OF ARIZONA
COLLEGE OF MEDICINE.
>> HOW DO YOU WRAP YOUR MIND
AROUND SOMETHING LIKE THIS?
WITH A GOOD DEAL OF HEARTBREAK
AND WITH THE UNDERSTANDING THAT
IT'S GOING TO TAKE AWHILE.
AND THAT THERE WILL BE PEOPLE
THAT WERE CLOSELY IMPACTED BY
THIS WHO WILL NEVER WRAP THEIR
MINDS AROUND THIS.
YOU KNOW, HUMAN MINDS ARE NOT
INFINITE.
YOU KNOW, THIS IS NOW APPEARING
TO BE PROBABLY THE WORST
SCHOOLYARD CATASTROPHE IN
HISTORY.
THERE'S GOING TO BE A HUGE,
LONG-TERM FALLOUT FOR THIS THAT
IS ALSO GOING TO IMPACT PEOPLE'S
EMOTIONAL WELL-BEING.
AND WE NEED TO GEAR OURSELVES UP
FOR THAT FALLOUT BECAUSE IT'S
COMING BECAUSE THIS IS A
HORRIBLE THING.
>> Reporter: THE NEWS OUT OF
NEWTOWN IS TRAUMATIC FOR PARENTS
AND CHILDREN.
THIS HAPPENED AT A SCHOOL WHERE
KIDS ARE SUPPOSED TO FEEL SAFE.
>> HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN TO THE
CHILDREN?
AGAIN, IT DEPENDS ON THE AGE OF
THE CHILD, BUT I THINK SIMPLE,
FORTHRIGHT EXPLANATIONS ARE THE
BEST.
AND I THINK ONE OF THE THINGS
THAT I TELL CHILDREN IS, THERE
ARE SOME BAD PEOPLE IN THE
WORLD.
AND SOMETIMES BAD PEOPLE DO
REALLY TERRIBLE THINGS.
AND A TERRIBLE THING HAS
HAPPENED AND THERE HAVE BEEN
SOME CHILDREN KILLED.
AND THIS IS TERRIBLE.
BUT YOU'RE SAFE.
AND, YOU KNOW -- YOU'RE SAFE,
AND YOU'RE IN A SITUATION NOW
WHERE YOU'RE NOT GOING TO BE
HARMED.
>> Reporter: THE AMERICAN
ACADEMY OF PEDIATRICS OFFERS
THIS ADVICE.
TAKE INTO ACCOUNT THE AGE OF THE
CHILD AND PROVIDE BASIC
INFORMATION WITHOUT OFFERING
DETAILS THAT MAY ONLY ALARM
THEM.
ASK YOUR CHILDREN WHAT THEY
ALREADY KNOW AND ANSWER
QUESTIONS.
PARENTS CAN SHARE THEIR OWN
FEELINGS IN THE WAYS THEY'RE
COPING AND FIND MEANINGFUL WAYS
TO HELP OTHERS.
>> CHILDREN ARE RESILIENT AND
WHAT REALLY MATTERS NOW IS HOW
WE HELP THEM UNDERSTAND WHAT'S
HAPPENED BUT EVEN I THINK MORE
IMPORTANT IS THE SENSE OF
PROTECTION AND SAFETY THAT WE
GIVE THEM STARTING THIS MOMENT
AND FOR THE NEXT WEEKS AN