COLLECT A SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE?
I MEAN, HIS MOTHER HAS BEEN
DESCRIBED BY SOME AS A
COLLECTOR.
WHY WOULD SOMEONE HAVE THAT KIND
OF A GUN?
I MEAN, THE THING IS MASSIVE
LOOKING.
>> THE BUSHMASTER, ACTUALLY, IS
ONE USED BY THE BELTWAY SNIPERS.
BUT IT IS -- IT'S CONSIDERED A
SPORTING WEAPON.
SOME PEOPLE SAY IT LOOKS LIKE AN
ASSAULT WEAPON, LOOKS LIKE A
MILITARY WEAPON.
BUT IT HAS CHARACTERISTICS THAT
MAKE IT SUITABLE FOR SPORTING
PURPOSES.
THEREFORE, IT WAS NEVER BANNED
UNDER THE OLD ASSAULT WEAPON
BAN, NOR IS IT BANNED BY THE
CONNECTICUT ASSAULT WEAPON BAN.
BUT AS FAR AS WHY SOMEBODY WOULD
WANT ONE OF THESE, A LOT OF
PEOPLE JUST BECAUSE THEY CAN
HAVE ONE.
SOME PEOPLE THINK IT'S SEXY TO
HAVE ONE OF THESE THINGS.
SOME PEOPLE FEEL IT'S FOR SELF
PROTECTION.
BUT IT'S WITHIN THE LAW TO HAVE
ONE SO PEOPLE FEEL THEY CAN DO
THAT.
>> MIKE BUSHARD WITH US THIS
EVENING.
DEB FEYERICK HAS OTHER STORIES
MAKING NEWS THIS EVENING.
DEB?
>> DOCTORS ARE MONITORING
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON FOR A CONCUSSION.
SHE HIT HER HEAD AFTER SHE
FAINTED.
HER OFFICE SAYS CLINTON WAS
DEHYDRATED FROM A STOMACH VIRUS.
SHE IS RESTING COMFORTABLY AT
HOME.
SHE'LL WORK AT HOME NEXT WEEK
FOLLOWING HER DOCTOR'S
RECOMMENDATIONS.
CLINTON WILL NOT TESTIFY AS HAD
BEEN SCHEDULED THURSDAY ABOUT
THE DEADLY ATTACK IN BENGHAZI,
LIBYA.
>>> IN SOUTH AFRICA, FORMER
PRESIDENT NELSON MANDELA IS
RECOVERING FROM SURGERY TO HAVE
GALLSTONES REMOVED.
MR. MANDELA HAS BEEN IN THE
HOSPITAL SINCE LAST WEEKEND DUE
TO A RECURRING LUNG INFECTION.
OFFICIALS SAY THE OPERATION
TODAY WAS A SUCCESS.
>>> IN EGYPT, PRESIDENT MOHAMED
MORSI CAST HIS BALLOT TODAY FOR
A NEW DRAFT CONSTITUTION.
VOTERS THERE DECIDING WHETHER
THE CONTROVERSIAL DOCUMENT WILL
GO INTO EFFECT.
THE DAYS LEADING UP TO TODAY'S
VOTE HAVE BEEN MARRED BY MANY
PROTESTS AND VIOLENCE.
BACK TO YOU, SOLEDAD.
>>> WE KNOW THAT THERE WAS A
REPORT THAT A RELATIVE OF THE
SHOOTER SAID THAT HE SUFFERED --
THE SHOOTER SUFFERED SOME,
QUOTE, KIND OF AUTISM.
WE WANT TO GET TO DR. MAC WH
WHIZNITSER, AN AUTISM EXPERT AT
A HOSPITAL IN CLEVELAND.
AND HE PROVIDED SOME MORE
CLARIFICATION FOR US ON THIS.
THANKS FOR BEING WITH US.
I APPRECIATE IT.
I THINK THIS BRINGS US INTO A
CONVERSATION ABOUT MENTAL
ILLNESS AND ABOUT SOMETHING ELSE
WHICH I GUESS IS DEVELOPMENTAL,
WHICH IS AUTISM.
MY NEPHEW IS AUTISTIC, SO I KNOW
A LITTLE BIT ABOUT THIS.
THERE ARE MANY PEOPLE WHO WOULD
SAY, WELL, WHAT IS A KIND OF
AUTISM -- WHICH IS QUOTING THE
GENTLEMAN WHO APPARENTLY TOLD
INVESTIGATORS THAT ABOUT THE
SHOOTER.
WHAT DO YOU THINK HE'S TALKING
ABOUT?
>> WELL, IF YOU LOOK AT THE
CLASSIC DEFINITION OF AUTISM OR
AUTISM SPECTRUM DISORDER, IT'S A
DEVELOPMENTAL PROBLEM, WHICH
MEANS YOU'RE BORN WITH A
TENDENCY, BUT IT MAY SHOW ITSELF
IN THE FIRST FEW YEARS OF LIFE.
IT'S A DEVELOPMENTAL PRONG THAT
AFFECTS YOUR SOCIALIZATION,
AFFECTS HOW YOU CAN COMMUNICATE
OR INTERACT WITH OTHER PEOPLE
AND HAS ASSOCIATED WITH IT SOME
REPETITIVE BEHAVIORS OR MAJOR
AREAS OF FASCINATION OR
INTEREST.
MORE RECENTLY, PEOPLE HAVE
ACTUALLY TAKEN THIS TERMINOLOGY
AND EXPANDED THE CONCEPT OF
AUTISM SPECTRUM DISORDER TO
REALLY SUGGEST PROBLEMS WITH
SOCIAL SKILLS OR SOCIAL BEHAVIOR
IN GENERAL.
SOMETIMES WITHOUT REALLY DIGGING
DOWN DEEP AND ASKING WHAT'S
DRIVING THEM.
AND I THINK IN THESE SITUATIONS,
WHEN SOMEONE MAKES THAT KIND OF
A STATEMENT, WE HAVE TO ASK ARE
THEY TALKING ABOUT SOMEONE WHO
HAS REALLY BEEN ANALYZED AND
EVALUATED CAREFULLY WITH A
CLEARCUT DIAGNOSIS OR JUST A
LABEL BEING PUT ON BECAUSE IT'S
A LABEL OF CONVENIENCE?
>> SANJAY EARLIER WAS TELLING ME
THERE IS NO CORRELATION THAT HE
NO, SIR OF ANY STUDIES HE'S
LOOKED AT THAT WOULD INDICATE
THAT PEOPLE WHO ARE AUTISTIC,
WHO HAVE AUTISM, MIGHT BE
CONNECTED WITH ANY KIND OF
VIOLENCE.
AND THAT MENTAL ILLNESS IS A
COMPLETELY DIFFERENT CATEGORY.
AND I THINK SOMETIMES, FRANKLY,
PEOPLE USE THEM UNDER THE SAME
CATEGORY, AS YOU SAY, KIND OF
GLOM THEM UNDER THE SAME TITLE.
WE DON'T KNOW MUCH ABOUT THE
SHOOTER.
THEY STILL HAVE NOT OFFICIALLY
IDENTIFIED HIM HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
BUT I GUESS I'M TRYING TO
UNDERSTAND.
IS THERE -- DOES HE HAVE A
MENTAL ILLNESS, AND IS THIS
SOMETHING THAT COULD BE --
PEOPLE COULD KNOW ABOUT AND
NOT -- AND HE COULD HAVE BEEN
STRUGGLING TO GET TREATMENT?
>> LET'S FIRST GET TO YOUR FIRST
POINT, WHICH IS IN AUTISM,
BETWEEN 25 AND 50% OF
INDIVIDUALS CAN HAVE AGGRESSIVE
OR VIOLENT BEHAVIORS.
BUT IN THOSE SITUATIONS, IT'S
ALMOST ALWAYS REACTIVE.
EITHER SOMETHING HURTS THEM OR
THEY DO SOMETHING IMPULSIVELY OR
BECAUSE THEY GET UPSET ABOUT
SOMETHING OR ANXIOUS OR MOODS
ARE NOT RIGHT.
IT'S REACTIVE, ON THE TIME AT
THAT SPOT.
BUT WE'RE TALKING ABOUT A
SITUATION HERE WHERE SOMETHING
WAS PREPLANNED.
WAS DELIBERATELY THOUGHT OUT.
DROVE A DISTANCE TO DO IT.
AND BASICALLY TARGETED
INDIVIDUALS WHO WERE CLEARLY
NOWHERE INVOLVED WITH ANYTHING
THAT'S GOING ON.
THAT'S A DIFFERENT TYPE OF
AGGRESSION.
THAT'S NOT REACTIVE AGGRESSION.
THAT'S MORE LIKE PREPLANNED
AGGRESSION THAT'S PRESENT.
THAT'S WHAT WE MAY SEE IN
INDIVIDUALS WITH MENTAL ILLNESS.
AND IN INDIVIDUALS WITH MENTAL
ILLNESS, YOU DON'T FIND THE
FEATURES OF IT FOR THE FIRST
TIME ON THE DAY THEY DO SUCH A
HEINOUS ACTION SUCH AS THIS.
SUCH A BAD ACTION SUCH AS THIS.
THEY'RE SYMPTOMATIC FOR A LONG
PERIOD OF TIME BEFOREHAND WHEN
THINGS ARE BREWING.
WE HAVE TO ASK WHAT MADE HIM
BASICALLY GO OVER THE EDGE AND I
THINK AS YOU HAVE ASKED RIGHTLY,
COULD SOMETHING HAVE BEEN DONE
BEFORE HAPPENED?
FOR ALL WE KNOW HE MAY HAVE BEEN
UNDER SOME CARE BUT THINGS MAY
HAVE CHANGED IN THIS TIME
PERIOD.
WE NEED MORE INFORMATION.
>> DOCTOR, I THINK YOU'RE RIGHT.
WE DO NEED MORE INFORMATION ON A
LOT OF FRONTS.
VERY LITTLE, AS I POINTED OUT,
IS KNOWN ABOUT THE SHOOTER AT
THIS POINT.
LAW ENFORCEMENT IS NOT EVEN
IDENTIFYING HIM YET.
THEY SAY THEY WAIT FOR THE
POSTMORTEM TO DO THAT
OFFICIALLY.
BUT WE'RE BEGINNING TO GET A
LITTLE BIT OF INFORMATION ABOUT
HIM.
AND SO WE'RE BRINGING IT TO YOU
AS WE GET IT.
WE'LL TAKE A SHORT BREAK.
AND WHEN HE COME BACK, WE'LL
CONTINUE TO BRING THE LATEST ON
THIS TERRIBLE, HORRIFIC SHOOTING
THAT HAPPENED AT A ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE BACK IN JUST A MOMENT.
STAY WITH US.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
JILL AND HER MOUTH HAVE LIVED
A GREAT LIFE.
BUT SHE HAS SOME DENTAL ISSUES
SHE'S NOT HAPPY ABOUT.
SO I INTRODUCED JILL
TO CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SELECTED FOR PEOPLE OVER 50.
PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE IS A
TOOTHPASTE THAT DEFENDS AGAINST
TENDER, INFLAMED GUMS,
SENSITIVITY AND WEAK ENAMEL.
CONDITIONS PEOPLE OVER 50
EXPERIENCE.
CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SO JILL CAN KEEP LIVING
THE GOOD LIFE.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
>>> ONE THING THAT IS VERY CLEAR
IS THAT THIS IS A VERY HARD
STORY TO WRAP OUR HEADS AROUND.
WHY WOULD SOMEONE SHOOT UP AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL?
AND IMAGINE WHAT THE PARENTS HAD
TO BE GOING THROUGH WHEN THEY
GOT A ROBOCALL, TELLING THEM
THERE WAS A SHOOTING AND
LOCKDOWN AT THEIR KIDS' SCHOOL.
EARLIER THIS MORNING, I TALKED
TO THE PARENTS OF TWO CHILDREN
WHO WERE IN THAT SCHOOL.
THOSE TWO CHILDREN LOST THEIR
PRINCIPAL AND SOME OF THEIR
CLOSE FRIENDS ARE DEAD.
HERE'S WHAT THEY TOLD ME.
>> WHEN I SAW THOSE TEACHERS,
WHEN I FOUND THE TWO CHILDREN
AND WE ARE DEVASTATED AND
HEARTBROKEN FOR THE POOR
FAMILIES WHO DID NOT HAVE THAT
MOMENT IN THE FIREHOUSE OF
FINDING THEIR CHILDREN, AND WE
CAN'T EVEN IMAGINE.
OUR PRAYERS.
THE ENTIRE COMMUNITY IS
HEARTBROKEN.
BUT WHEN I SAW THOSE TEACHERS
AND I LOCKED EYES WITH EACH OF
THEM SEPARATELY, WHEN I FOUND
THE TWO CHILDREN, IF I COULD GO
BACK, I WOULD -- I WOULD EMBRACE
THEM.
BECAUSE I HAD NO IDEA WHAT THEY
HAD GONE THROUGH.
BUT IT WAS ACTUALLY HANDLED VERY
WELL, BECAUSE I CAN'T IMAGINE
THE PANDEMONIUM THAT WOULD HAVE
BEEN GOING ON IN THAT FIREHOUSE,
FROM THE PARENTS SEARCHING FOR
THEIR CHILDREN.
IF ANYBODY THERE HAD ANY IDEA
THE LEVEL OF WHAT HAD HAPPENED
YESTERDAY, PEOPLE JUST SIMPLY
DIDN'T KNOW REALLY WHAT WAS
GOING ON.
THEY JUST KNEW THAT THEIR
CHILDREN HAD BEEN IN A DANGEROUS
PLACE, AND THAT THOSE THAT MADE
IT TO THE FIREHOUSE WERE, THANK
GOD, SAFE.
>> WHAT ARE YOU TELL YOUR SON,
WHO IS A FIRST GRADER?
WHAT WILL YOU TELL YOUR DAUGHTER
WHO IS A THIRD GRADER?
DO THEY HAVE I DIDN'T ANY IDEA
OF HOW SCOPE OF HOW BAD IT IS?
>> I THINK THEY DO.
WE HAVEN'T REALLY LET ON.
WE HAVEN'T SAID MUCH.
THIS IS SHOCKING, SO THIS IS NEW
TO US.
AND WE'RE DEFINITELY GOING TO
TALK TO COUNSELORS TODAY OVER AT
THE REED SCHOOL.
WE'RE GOING TO LIVE AT OUR
CHURCH AT SAINT ROSE, AND WE'RE
JUST GOING TO LEARN WHAT TO SAY
BEFORE WE SAY IT.
IT'S REALLY TRICKY.
AND FOR MY THIRD GRADER, LITTLE
BITS AND PIECES ARE COMING OUT
NOW.
>> SHE'S HANDLING IT A LITTLE --
IT SOUNDS LIKE SHE IS NOT
TALKING AS MUCH ABOUT IT.
>> NO.
LITTLE THINGS ARE COMING OUT
NOW, WHERE SHE -- SHE HEARD A
LOT.
THEY ALL HEARD AND SAW THINGS
THAT OUR CHILDREN SHOULD NOT
HEAR OR SEE.
AND SO WE JUST -- THEY KNOW THAT
IT WAS A BAD MAN.
AND WE SAID WE'RE JUST COMING TO
TALK TO PEOPLE.
THEY WANT TO KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
OVER AT SANDY HOOK.
THEY DON'T KNOW -- THEY DON'T
KNOW THAT THEY'VE LOST THEIR
FRIENDS AND THEIR PRINCIPAL.
>> IT'S BECOME APPARENT THAT OUR
6-YEAR-OLD HAS LOST CLOSE
FRIENDS.
AND HE'S VERY UNAWARE OF THAT
RIGHT NOW.
WE DON'T KNOW HOW TO EXACTLY
APPROACH IT WITH HIM AT THIS
POINT.
THE WE'RE JUST KIND OF GUARDING
THEM FROM THE TV.
WHEN THEY FELL ASLEEP LAST
NIGHT, AND -- AND THE EXPERTS
WOULD COME ON THE TV TO DISCUSS
HOW YOU TALK TO YOUR CHILDREN,
WE WERE VERY ATTENTIVE.
LIKE, OH, LET'S LISTEN, OR LET'S
WATCH THIS.
AND WE REALIZED WATCHING IT, IT
HAD NOTHING TO DO WITH US.
IT HAD EVERYTHING TO DO WITH THE
REST OF THE COUNTRY WATCHING IT.
BUT NOT THE PEOPLE THAT WERE
INVOLVED AND THE CHILDREN THAT
WERE ACTUALLY IN THE SCHOOL.
SO IT'S IMPORTANT FOR US TO --
WE REALIZE, AS THIS GOES ON,
IT'S IMPORTANT FOR US TO TAKE
ADVANTAGE OF THE COUNSELING.
>> MANY PEOPLE HAVE SENT
MESSAGES TO ME TO TELL PEOPLE
LIKE YOU AND THE PEOPLE WHO HAVE
LOST THEIR CHILDREN JUST SORRY
THEY FEEL FOR THEM.
>> YEAH, I MEAN, YOUR HEART --
THIS IS A FEELING -- IT IS
UNSPEAKABLE.
IT IS LIKE REACHING INTO YOUR
INSIDES AND PULLING THEM OUT.
I MEAN, WHEN THINGS HAPPEN TO
YOUR CHILDREN, AND TO OTHER
PEOPLE -- I MEAN, I CAN'T LOOK
AT MY CHILDREN'S FACES NOW
WITHOUT SEEING THE FACES OF
EVERY ONE OF THEIR SCHOOL MATES.
AND ALL OF THEIR FRIENDS.
AND EVERYTHING THAT THEY'RE
DOING RIGHT NOW OR SAYING OR
TALKING ABOUT CHRISTMAS AND JUST
THINKING -- THEIR FRIENDS SHOULD
ALL BE HERE.
AND IT'S JUST -- IT IS SUCH --
IT IS SO HEAVY.
SO HEAVY ON YOUR HEART.
AND --
>> THE NATION FEELS THAT WAY
TOO.
>> YEAH.
THE OUTPOURING OF LOVE HAS BEEN
TREMENDOUS.
I MEAN, PEOPLE ARE CALLING FROM
ALL OVER THE WORLD.
AND WE'RE GOING TO NEED THAT
NOW.
WE'RE GOING TO ABSOLUTELY NEED
THAT TO BE THERE AS A COMMUNITY.
WE LOVE SANDY HOOK.
I MEAN, THIS IS SUCH A GREAT
PLACE.
AND THE PEOPLE ARE WONDERFUL.
AND WE'RE JUST GOING TO HAVE TO
REALLY EMBRACE EACH OTHER AND
OPEN OUR HEARTS AND OPEN OUR
ARMS AND OPEN THOSE CHURCH DOORS
AND JUST GET EVERYBODY PRAYING
AND TOGETHER.
BECAUSE I MEAN, I THINK THIS IS
SOMETHING WE WILL GET THROUGH.
I DON'T THINK THIS IS SOMETHING
WE WILL EVER, EVER GET OVER.
>> I WOULD LIKE -- I WOULD LIKE
ALSO TO SAY THAT WE ALWAYS FELT
BLESSED THAT OUR CHILDREN WERE
AT SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
IT WAS AN ABSOLUTELY BEAUTIFUL
SCHOOL, FANTASTIC EDUCATORS.
THE PRINCIPAL WHO, GOD BLESS
HER, LOST HER LIFE, WAS JUST --
A VERY SPECIAL PERSON.
AND ALL THE PARENTS KNEW THAT.
SO IT'S A VERY -- IT'S SHOCKING
BEYOND BELIEF THAT THIS HAS
HAPPENED.
AND IT'S -- I MEAN, WE'RE JUST
GRIEF-STRICKEN, HEARTBROKEN FOR
THOSE FAMILIES.
>> THE PHELPS FAMILY, WITH TWO
CHILDREN, A FIRST GRADER AND A
THIRD GRADER.
GRAPPLING NOW WITH HOW TO DEAL
WITH THIS AFTERMATH AND FEELING
SO LUCKY AT THE SAME TIME.
THEIR CHILDREN WERE AMONG THE
SURVIVORS OF THIS HORRIFIC,
HORRIFIC SHOOTING.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE MORE TO TALK
ABOUT AS WE CONTINUE.
THOSE CHILDREN WERE AT THE
SCHOOL AT THE TIME OF THE
SHOOTING, CERTAINLY HAVE A LOT
TO TALK ABOUT AND QUESTIONS
THEY'RE GOING TO WANT TO ASK AND
ANSWER AS THEY WOULD LIKE TO GET
ANSWERED.
LET'S GET TO DOCTOR JEFF
GARDERE.
HE HAS BEEN TALKING A LOT ABOUT
WHAT ANSWERS PARENTS NEED TO BE
GIVING THEIR CHILDREN.
HE'S A CLINICAL PSYCHOLOGIST.
SO, JEFF, I DID THAT INTERVIEW
WITH THE -- THOSE PARENTS A
LITTLE BIT EARLIER TODAY.
AND THEY WERE STRUGGLING.
THEY LITERALLY DID NOT KNOW THE
WORDS TO USE TO BE ABLE TO TELL
THEIR FIRST GRADE SON THAT SOME
OF HIS CLASSMATES AND HIS GOOD
FRIENDS HAD BEEN KILLED.
HOW DO PEOPLE WHO ARE IN THE
SITUATION HANDLE THIS?
HOW DO THOSE OF US WHO ARE
OUTSIDE OF IT AND HAVE CHILDREN
THAT ARE DEALING WITH IT HANDLE
IT AS WELL?
>> WELL, I HEARD WHAT THEY SAID,
AND IT WAS VERY POIGNANT.
THEY HAD LISTENED TO THE EXPERTS
SUCH AS MYSELF GIVING ADVICE.
IF YOU HAVE CHILDREN WHO HAVE
HEARD ABOUT THIS, HOW TO SPEAK
WITH THEM.
THIS IS A VERY SPECIAL
POPULATION.
THEY'RE THE ONES THAT ARE AT THE
GROUND ZERO WHO HAVE BEEN
TRAUMATIZED.
AND I WOULD TELL THOSE PARENTS,
AND THIS IS SPECIFICALLY FOR YOU
THERE IN CONNECTICUT, AS PART OF
SANDY HOOK.
THE MOST IMPORTANT THING IS LET
YOUR CHILDREN KNOW THAT YOU, AS
THE PARENTS, HAVE BEEN VERY HURT
BY THIS.
AND THAT YOU WANT TO CRY, AND
IT'S OKAY TO CRY.
AND IT'S OKAY TO GRIEVE.
BUT MOST IMPORTANT, THEY, AS THE
PARENTS, SOLEDAD, HAVE TO
PROVIDE THE STABILITY OF JUST
BEING THERE WITH THEIR CHILDREN,
HUGGING THEM, HOLDING THEM,
LETTING THEM KNOW THAT THEY ARE
SAFE RIGHT NOW, AND JUST
LISTENING TO WHATEVER IT IS THAT
THOSE CHILDREN WANT TO SAY.
AND JUST BEING THAT EAR MORE
THAN ANYTHING ELSE.
>> IS IT YOUR EXPECTATION THAT
EVERYONE IN THIS COMMUNITY OR --
WILL HAVE PTSD?
OR WILL IT JUST BE THOSE THAT
HAD CHILDREN IN THE SCHOOL
SYSTEM?
CAN PEOPLE WHO DIDN'T EXPERIENCE
IT BUT ARE EXPERIENCING IT FROM
A DISTANCE ALSO GET PTSD?
>> WELL, I WOULD SAY THAT THE
PEOPLE WHO ARE PART OF THE
SCHOOL, PART OF THAT COMMUNITY,
THEY'RE LOOKING AT THE
STATISTICS.
YOU'VE HEARD IT FROM DR. SANJAY
GUPTA.
THERE'S ALMOST A 70% PROBABILITY
THAT THEY WILL HAVE SOME SORT OF
PTSD.
IT WILL LAST FOR MONTHS, IF NOT
YEARS.
HOWEVER, THE IMPORTANT THING IS
THE MOBILE CRISIS UNITS ARE
THERE.
TRAINED POLICE OFFICERS, SOCIAL
WORKERS ARE THERE.
SO THE QUICKER YOU ADDRESS THE
ISSUES AND LET THEM SPEAK ABOUT
THIS, THE BETTER THE PROGNOSIS
IN THE FUTURE.
FOR THOSE PARENTS WHO ARE
DEALING WITH THEIR KIDS, WHO ARE
OUTSIDE OF THAT COMMUNITY, THE
MOST IMPORTANT THING IS THAT YOU
LISTEN TO WHAT IT IS THAT THEY
KNOW.
ASK THEM WHAT THEY KNOW.
ASK THEM WHAT THEY WANT TO
DISCUSS.
AND IT'S NOT ONE CONVERSATION,
SOLEDAD.
IT'S A SERIES OF CONVERSATIONS
WHILE YOU'RE DOING THINGS THAT
THEY ENJOY.
JUST BE THERE AND LISTEN TO WHAT
IT IS THAT THEY HAVE TO SAY, AND
LET THEM KNOW THAT THEY WILL BE
SAFE IN THEIR SCHOOLS.
THERE ARE NO GUARANTEES, BUT
EMPOWER THEM WITH THE KNOWLEDGE
THEY CAN BE STRONG AND THEY CAN
SYMPATHIZE AND EMPATHIZE WITH
THOSE CHILDREN THAT HAVE LOST
THEIR LIVES.
BUT AS FOR THEM AND THEIR
FAMILIES, WE ARE THERE FOR THEM.
THE STABILITY IS THERE.
>> DR. JEFF GARDERE.
JEFF, THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR THE
INFORMATION, THE ADVICE.
WE APPRECIATE IT.
AND WE'RE LEARNING SOME NEW
DETAILS ABOUT THE SUSPECTED
SHOOTER'S MOTHER, NANCY LANZA.
WE ARE TOLD THAT SHE LIKED TO
GARDEN, SHE PLAYED A DICE GAME
CALLED BUNKO WITH HER
GIRLFRIENDS.
A NEIGHBOR SAID THE LANZAS
LOOKED LIKE A NICE AND NORMAL
FAMILY.
POLICE SAY, THOUGH, THAT NANCY'S
SON, THE SHOOTER, KILLED HER IN
HER NEWTON HOME BEFORE HE WENT
ON TO THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AND CNN'S DAVID ARIESTO JOINS ME
NOW.
YOU HAD AN OPPORTUNITY TO GO TO
THE NEIGHBORHOOD WHERE NOT ONLY
IS IT CENTER OF AN
INVESTIGATION.
THERE ARE MANY NEIGHBORS WHO
HAVE TOLD YOU ABOUT THE FAMILY,
AS WELL.
WHAT ARE THEY TELLING YOU?
>> YOU SPEAK TO NEIGHBORS, IT
PAINTS A PICTURE OF THIS AFLUENT
COMMUNITY THAT IS IN
SOUTHWESTERN CONNECTICUT.
AND IT'S -- THIS WOMAN WHO OFTEN
WOULD BE WITH HER BOYS, THEY
MOVED TO THE AREA IN 1998.
THE -- SHE DIVORCED WITH HER
HUSBAND YEARS LATER.
BUT THEY WOULD OFTEN ATTEND
THESE PARTIES, THESE DICE GAMES
IN WHICH THEY WERE GARDENING IN
THE BACK AND TALK ABOUT
LANDSCAPING.
THE COMMON JOKE THAT ONE OF THE
NEIGHBORS MENTIONED, YOU'RE
DOING ALL THIS LANDSCAPING
BEHIND THE HOUSE, NOBODY IS
GOING TO SEE THIS.
BUT IT WAS THIS IDEA THAT THIS
WOMAN WAS A -- A PLEASANT,
PLEASURABLE PERSON TO BE AROUND.
SHE WAS SOMEONE WHO WAS INVOLVED
IN THE COMMUNITY.
AND YOU TALK TO RESIDENTS HERE,
AND IT'S REALLY -- THIS SENSE OF
THIS TIGHT KNIT COMMUNITY.
WE TALK TO OTHER PEOPLE EARLIER
IN THE DAY, AND MANY PEOPLE SAY
THAT PEOPLE MOVE TO THIS AREA
BECAUSE OF THE SCHOOL SYSTEM.
SO TO HAVE SOMETHING LIKE THIS
TAKE PLACE AT A SCHOOL,
PARTICULARLY IN AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, HAS JUST ROCKED THIS
COMMUNITY.
>> THERE ARE SO MANY PEOPLE WHO
ASK THE QUESTION WHY.
WERE NEIGHBORS ABLE TO TELL YOU
ANYTHING ABOUT THE BOYS IN THE
FAMILIAR LYRICS , SPECIFICALLY
THE YOUNG MAN WHO WOULD GO ON TO
BE THE SHOOTER.
>> ONE OF THE THINGS THEY
MENTIONED, THEY DIDN'T SEE THE
BOYS.
THEY MOVED THERE IN 1998 AND
LIVED THERE REALLY UP UNTIL THIS
WEEK.
THE FATHER DIVORCED YEARS LATER.
BUT THE BOYS WERE NOT
INDIVIDUALS THEY SAW VERY OFTEN.
AND THIS PICTURE THAT YOU ALSO
GET IS THAT YOU HAVE THIS ONE
INDIVIDUAL WHO IS GARDENING AND
PLAYING CARDS AND PLAYING DICE.
AND AT THE SAME TIME, YOU HAVE
WHAT APPEARS TO BE SEVERAL GUNS
WITHIN THIS HOUSE, SOME OF THOSE
GUNS BEING HIGH-POWERED WEAPONS.
SO IT'S THIS CONFLICTING
ACCOUNT.
AND ONE OF THE NEIGHBORS
PROBABLY SAID IT BEST.
THERE'S SOMETHING MISSING HERE.
>> IT'S INTERESTING.
IT APPEARS, RIGHT, SHE WOULD BE
A COLLECTOR, SOME OF THE PEOPLE
WE HAVE SPOKEN TO, WHEN YOU LOOK
AT THE CALIBER OF THE GUNS AND
THE RANGE, THE KINDS OF WEAPONS
SHE HAD, SHE WOULD BE A
COLLECTOR.
DID THE NEIGHBORS TALK ABOUT HER
PASSION FOR COLLECTING WEAPONS
AT ALL?
DID THEY KNOW ABOUT IT?
>> YOU KNOW, I ASKED THAT
QUESTION SPECIFICALLY AND
CATEGORICALLY, EACH NEIGHBOR I
TALKED TO SAID NO.
SO IT'S -- YOU KNOW, IT PAINTS A
BIT OF A CONFUSING PICTURE WHEN
YOU HAVE THESE TYPE OF WEAPONS
THAT APPARENTLY WERE HERS.
AND WERE USED IN THIS TERRIBLE
TRAGEDY.
>> CRAZY.
SO THERE WAS A QUESTION ABOUT
EARLY ON WHEN THIS STORY BROKE,
THERE WAS WORD SHE WAS A TEACHER
IN THE SCHOOL.
AND WE NOW KNOW THAT WAS NOT THE
CASE.
SHE WAS NOT A TEACHER IN THE
SCHOOL, BUT THAT SHE MIGHT HAVE
SOME AFFILIATION WITH THE
SCHOOL.
WHAT HAVE YOU BEEN ABLE TO LEARN
ON THAT FRONT?
>> YOU KNOW, WHEN SHE
DIVORCED -- THERE WAS
SPECULATION WITHIN THE COMMUNITY
THAT SHE MIGHT HAVE USED HER
MAIDEN NAME AND MAY HAVE DONE
SOME SUBSTITUTE TEACHING.
THAT WAS PRETTY MUCH BATTED DOWN
BY MOST OF THE SCHOOL
AUTHORITIES WE TALKED TO AND
OTHERS.
SO IT WAS REALLY UNCLEAR WHAT
SHE WAS DOING.
SHE CERTAINLY HAD TAKEN SOME
TIME OFF AFTER WORKING IN
FINANCE.
AND SHE HAD ESSENTIALLY GOT VERY
MUCH INTO GARDENING.
VERY MUCH INTO LANDSCAPING.
WHAT HER CONNECTION WAS WITH THE
SCHOOL, IF ANY, IS UNCLEAR.
>> IT IS SUCH -- SO MANY
QUESTIONS TO BE ASKED.
WE'VE HEARD SO MUCH
CONTRADICTORY INFORMATION
THROUGHOUT -- REALLY, IT'S BEEN
WHAT, 30-PLUS HOURS NOW THAT
WE'VE BEEN COVERING THIS STORY.
AND THERE'S SO MANY QUESTIONS
AND SO FEW ANSWERS ABOUT THE
SHOOTER, HIS FAMILY.
ANY MOTIVATION.
YOU KNOW, I GUESS AS LAW
ENFORCEMENT SAYS, THEY WILL
RELEASE MORE INFORMATION ABOUT
HIM AS SOON AS THEY'RE DONE WITH
THAT MOST MORE ITEM, WHICH WILL
BE TOMORROW MORNING.
DAVID, THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR THE
REPORT.
NO DOUBT, THOUGH, HERE TODAY SO
MANY PEOPLE ARE OVERWHELMED WITH
SO MUCH PAIN.
JUST TO TALK TO PEOPLE IN THE
STREETS WHO HAVE COME TO THE
MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS WHERE
THEY'RE LAYING FLOWERS OR
LIGHTING VOTE ACTIVE CANDLES,
MISSING THE LOVED ONES, PEOPLE
THEY KNOW THEY HAVE LOST, TRYING
TO UNDERSTAND WHAT'S HAPPENED.
TRYING TO MAKE SENSE OF
SOMETHING LIKE THIS PROBABLY IS
IMPOSSIBLE.
>> THIS IS A VERY, VERY TRAGIC,
TRAGIC SCENE FOR EVERYBODY.
CERTAINLY OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN
FOR THE FAMILIES HERE.
>> WELL, ABOUT 9:30, 9:40, WE
HEARD NOISES AND THE
ANNOUNCEMENT SYSTEM WAS STILL ON
SO -- IT DIDN'T GO OFF, SO YOU
HEAR WHAT SOUNDED LIKE POPS,
GUNSHOTS.
>> YOU HEARD A TEACHER MANAGED
TO TAKE TWO CHILDREN OUT OF THE
HALLWAY, PULL THEM INTO THE
CLASSROOM, LOCK THE DOOR, AND
MOVE EVERYBODY OVER TO THE OTHER
SIDE OF THE ROOM.
>> WE JUST TOLD A LITTLE BOY
ABOUT HIS SISTER NOW, JUST AS --
WHO AM I GOING TO PLAY WITH, HE
SAID.
I HAVE NOBODY TO PLAY WITH, HE
>> WHEN YOUR FIRST GRADER GOES
TO BED AND SAYS "MOMMY, IS
ANYONE FROM MY CLASS LAST YEAR,
ARE THEY OKAY?
ARE THEY ALL OKAY?"
AND YOU LOOK AT THEM AND SAY I'M
NOT REALLY SURE.
>> YOU CAN NEVER BE PREPARED FOR
THIS KIND OF INCIDENT.
WHAT HAS HAPPENED, WHAT HAS
TRANSPIRED AT THAT SCHOOL
BUILDING WILL LEAVE A MARK ON
THIS COMMUNITY, AND EVERY FAMILY
IMPACTED.
>> WE ARE ON THE VERGE OF
WRAPPING UP OUR COVERAGE RIGHT
NOW, BUT WE'RE GOING TO
CONTINUE, OBVIOUSLY, CNN'S
COVERAGE OF THIS TRAGEDY IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
DEB FEYERICK, THERE ARE SO MANY
QUESTIONS YET TO BE ANSWERED.
WE'LL KNOW MORE TOMORROW,
CERTAINLY, WHEN LAW ENFORCEMENT
TELLS US AND THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER'S OFFICE TELLS US.
THAT THEY WILL FINISH THE
POSTMORTEMS THAT WILL BE DONE ON
THE SHOOTER AND HIS MOTHER.
AND THAT WILL BRING AN END TO
THE -- I GUESS THE INVESTIGATION
INTO THE BODIES, AT LEAST, AT
THE CRIME SCENE.
>> SURE.
AND THE THING IS ALSO, PEOPLE
ARE SAYING, WELL, WHAT WAS THE
MOTIVE, WHAT IS THE MOTIVE?
WHAT WOULD DRIVE SOMEBODY LIKE
THIS TO KILL HIS OWN MOTHER?
AND THEN TO OPEN FIRE ON A
SCHOOL FILLED WITH INNOCENT
CHILDREN.
THE ANSWER, IT'S ALMOST
IRRELEVANT.
THE FACT THAT IT HAPPENED IS
WHAT'S SO DEVASTATING TO SO MANY
PEOPLE.
AND EVEN THE TOWN SAYING, IN THE
NICEST WAY POSSIBLE, LET US BE,
LET US HEAL.
I THINK EVERYBODY WANTS TO HEAL.
IF THAT'S EVEN POSSIBLE,
SOLEDAD.
>> YOU KNOW, THERE'S NO QUESTION
ABOUT THAT.
I DON'T KNOW THAT THEY'LL EVER
KNOW REALLY WHY.
YOU KNOW, PEOPLE HAVE TOLD US --
THEY MIGHT KNOW THE HOW.
THEY MIGHT EVENTUALLY BE ABLE TO
UNDERSTAND WITH LAW ENFORCEMENT
LAYING OUT THE -- HOW IT
HAPPENED.
BUT THEY MAY NEVER ACTUALLY
UNDERSTAND THE WHY.
DEB FEYERICK, THANKS SO MUCH FOR
BEING PART OF THIS COVERAGE.
CNN WILL CONTINUE THE COVERAGE
OF THIS TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WE'LL TAKE A SHORT BREAK FIRST,
AND WE'RE BACK WITH THIS
COVERAGE RIGHT AFTER THE BREAK.
STAY WITH US.
ñ?
>>> WE'RE VERY LUCKY THAT ALL
THE CHILDREN, MY SON INCLUDED,
HAD THE PRESENCE OF MIND TO
REACT APPROPRIATELY, AND THEY
BASICALLY RAN RIGHT NEXT TO THE
GUY, OUT THE DOOR.
>> THEY RAN PAST THE GUNMAN.
>> THEY RAN -- HE'S STILL
STANDING IN THE DOOR.
AND THEY RAN PAST HIM.
>> HERE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
YOU'RE ABOUT TO HEAR AMAZING,
AMAZING STORIES OF SURVIVAL.
HEART BREAKING STORIES OF
SACRIFICE.
AND ANSWERS THAT ONLY LEAD TO
MORE QUESTIONS.
I'M WOLF BLITZER.