>> BUT I WAS SUCH A NICE JEWISH
GIRL, THAT I SAID, MARLON, I
CAN'T STAY OVERFLIGHT WITH YOU.
I I WILL GO WITH YOU FOR THE DAY
BUT YOU HAVE TO TAKE ME HOME.
>> SO MARLON CLEARLY WANTED TO
DO MORE THAN SEE THE FLOWERS
WITH YOU.
>> HE WANTED TO SLEEP IN THE
DESERT WITH ME.
>> YOU TURNED DOWN MARLON
BRANDO?
>> YEAH, ABSOLUTELY.
>> HOW DID HE TAKE REJECTION?
>> IT WAS FINE.
>> A REMARKABLE CONVERSATION
WITH A REMARKABLE LADY.
BARBRA STREISAND WITH ME FOR THE
HOUR TOMORROW NIGHT AT 9:00 P.M.
EAST PERSON THAT'S ALL FOR
TONIGHT.
AC 360 STARTS NOW.
BREAKING NEWS TONIGHT.
THE WOMAN BELIEVED TO BE
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S CHOICE FOR
SECRETARY OF STATE SAYS NO
THANKS.
U.N. AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE.
SHE WAS THE ONE CAUGHT UP IN THE
CONTROVERSY OF HER STATEMENTS
AFTER THE MURDER OF FOUR
AMERICANS IN LIBYA.
YOU WILL RECALL THE PRESIDENT
STOOD UP FOR HER USING BLUNT
LANGUAGE SAYING ANYONE WHO HAS A
PROBLEM WITH HER HAS A PROBLEM
WITH HIM.
INSTEAD THERE WON'T BE
CONFRONTATION BECAUSE AMBASSADOR
RICE TOOK HERSELF OUT OF
CONTENTION WRITING THE PRESIDENT
SHE IS HONORED TO BE CONSIDERED
FOR THE OFFICE SAYING, I AM NOW
CONVINCED THAT THE CONFIRMATION
PROCESS WOULD BE LENGTHY,
DISRUPTIVE AND COSTLY AND THAT
TRADE-OFF IS SIMPLY NOT WORTH IT
TO OUR COUNTRY.
>> TODAY I MADE THE DECISION
THAT IT WAS THE BEST THING FOR
OUR COUNTRY, FOR THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE, THAT I CONTINUE TO BE
CRED BY THE PRESIDENT FOR
NOMINATION OF SECRETARY OF STATE
BECAUSE I DIDN'T WANT TO SEE A
CONFIRMATION PROCESS THAT WAS
VERY PROLONGED, VERY
POLITICIZED, VERY DISTRACTING,
AND VERY DISRUPTIVE BECAUSE
THERE ARE SO MANY THINGS WE NEED
TO GET DONE AS A COUNTRY AND THE
FIRST SEVERAL MONTHS OF THE
PRESIDENT'S AGENDA IS REALLY THE
OPPORTUNITY TO GET THE CRUCIAL
THINGS DONE, WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION
REFORM, BALANCED DEFICIT
REDUCTION, JOB CREATION.
THAT'S WHAT MATTERS.
AND TO THE EXTENT MY NOMINATION
COULD HAVE DELAYED, DISTRACTED
OR DEFLECTED PRIORITIES
IMPOSSIBLE TO ACHIEVE I DIDN'T
WANT THAT AND I WOULD MUCH
PREFER TO CONTINUE DOING WHAT
I'M DOING, WHICH IS A JOB I LOVE
AT THE UNITED NATIONS.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA ACCEPTED HER
DECISION TO BOW OUT CALLING HER
AN EXTRAORDINARILY PATRIOTIC
PERSON.
WITH MORE ON WHO LED UP TO THAT
DECISION, DANA, WHAT WAS THE
PIVOTAL MOMENT FOR ALL OF THIS
FOR AMBASSADOR RICE?
>> FIRST OF ALL WITH HER CHIEF
FOES, SENATORS, McCAIN, GRAHAM
AND AYOTE.
BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY A
REPUBLICAN WHO HADN'T QUITE MADE
UP HER MIND.
THAT THE MODERATE REPUBLICAN
FROM MAINE, SUSAN COLLINS.
BY ALL ACCOUNTS THAT MEETING DID
NOT GO WELL AT ALL ACCORDING TO
A SOURCE FAMILIAR WITH THAT
MEETING.
SHE REALLY DIDN'T WANT TO ANSWER
REALLY BASIC QUESTIONS AND GOT
FRUSTRATED AND MAYBE EVEN A
LITTLE PRICKLY AT SOME OF THE
BASIC QUESTIONS AND AFTER THAT,
THE FEELING, EVEN AMONG
DEMOCRATS WHO TALKED TO
REPUBLICANS IS THEY WEREN'T SURE
IF SHE CAN'T HANDLE MEETINGS
WITH U.S. SENATORS, HOW IS SHE
GOING TO BE ON THE WORLD STAGE
REPRESENTING THE U.S. THERE.
SO THAT DEFINITELY WAS AN ISSUE.
THERE'S NO QUESTION THAT THE
PRESIDENT IN HIS STATEMENT MADE
CLEAR THAT HE DIDN'T THINK SUSAN
RICE WAS TREATED FAIRLY.
THERE ARE NO QUESTIONS THAT
POLITICS WERE AT PLAY HERE.
SHE ILLUSTRATED THAT.
BUT IT WAS MORE THAN THAT.
ALSO PERSONALITY DRIVEN.
EVEN DEMOCRATS THINK SHE IS VERY
SMART, VERY CAPABLE BUT DOESN'T
HAVE THE RIGHT PERSONALITY FOR
THIS JOB.
>> GLORIA, EARLIER I HEARD YOU
SAY THAT AMBASSADOR RICE WAS
PROBABLY UNDERESTIMATED BY THE
CLUB.
WHAT DID YOU MEAN FROM THAT?
>> THAT WAS FROM A DEMOCRAT
CLOSE TO THE WHITE HOUSE WHO
SAYS THE CLUB IS REALLY
IMPORTANT ON CAPITOL HILL.
JOHN KERRY IS THE LEADER IN THAT
CLUB.
JOHN McCAIN LIKES HIM AN AWFUL
LOT AND WOULD CLEARLY GO ALONG
WITH THAT NOMINATION.
ALSO WHEN SHE TRAVELED UP THERE,
AND SHE WANTED TO GO UP THERE TO
TALK TO THESE SENATORS, THERE IS
A SENSE FROM THE SOURCE THAT SHE
OVER HER ABILITY TO WOO THEM
OVER.
THAT WAS A BIG PREEXISTING
CONDITION FOR HER.
AS DANA JUST POINTED OUT, SHE
DIDN'T WIN OVER SUSAN COLLINS
WHO WAS QUITE IMPORTANT TO HER.
>> DAVID, WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF
THIS?
IS THIS JUST A SIGN OF HOW
PARTISAN THINGS HAVE BECOME OR
WAS IT PRETTY CLEAR FROM AS SOON
AS THE CONTROVERSY OVER
BENGHAZI, THE COMMENTS BEGAN
THAT IT WASN'T GOING TO HAPPEN?
>> I DON'T THINK THIS IS JUST
ABOUT PARTISANSHIP.
AND I DON'T THINK IT IS JUST
GOOD BENGHAZI.
THAT WAS AN ISSUE OF COURSE.
BUT IN THIS CASE, THERE ARE A
NUMBER OF SENATORS ON BOTH SIDES
TO THE AISLE THAT BELIEVE THE
UNITED STATES HAS TOUGH WORK
AHEAD IN INTERNATIONAL
RELATIONS.
SOMEONE HAS TO NEGOTIATE WITH
THE IRANIANS TO MAKE SURE WE
DON'T GET INTO A CONFLICT THERE
AND SOMEONE WITH A TOUGHNESS AND
AUTHORITY OF A JIM BAKER AND
FRANKLY, THERE WAS A SENSE ABOUT
SUSAN RICE THAT EVEN THOUGH SHE
IS VERY TALENTED AND I THINK SHE
DID A GENEROUS THING TODAY BY
WITHDRAWING, SHE REALLY WAS
LOYAL TO HER PRESIDENT BY HIM
DOING THAT.
BUT THERE WAS ALSO A SENSE THAT
SHE DIDN'T HAVE THE WEIGHT.
SHE DIDN'T HAVE THE BACKGROUND
THAT SENATOR KERRY DOES.
AND HE IS EXTREMELY SCHOOLED AND
KNOWS THE ROUGH PARTS OF THE
WORLD.
THERE WAS A SENSE IN THE SENATE
THAT PEOPLE THERE WOULD JUST BE
MORE COMFORTABLE WITH HIM
REPRESENTING THE UNITED STATES.
>> DAVID, WHAT DO YOU THINK THIS
SAYS ABOUT PRESIDENT OBAMA
HIMSELF.
IT SEEMS LIKE, ESPECIALLY IN THE
LAST MONTH OR SO, THAT HE WAS
DIGGING IN HIS HEELS PREPARING
FOR A FIGHT.
>> WELL, IT DID SEEM LIKE THAT.
AND THERE WAS ALSO, YOU KNOW,
THERE HAVE BEEN VARIOUS REPORTS
THAT HE'S BEEN AGONIZING OVER
THIS CHOICE AND IN A SENSE SHE
LET HIM OFF AND RECOGNIZING A
KNEE AND REMOVED IT.
AND I -- BUT I THINK ONE CAN
READ INTO THIS, THAT HE DOESN'T
WANT A SERIES OF FIGHTS WITH
REPUBLICANS ACROSS THE BOARD.
HE'S GOT A BIG FIGHT ON HIS
HANDS ON THE FISCAL CLIFF.
AND YOU KNOW, IT MAY BE JUST ONE
STRUGGLE TOO MANY WHEN HE WANTS
IT GET HIS SECOND TERM OFF AND
RUNNING AND HE DOESN'T WANT TO
BE ENSNARED LIKE THIS.
IT HAPPENS TO PRESIDENTS AND AS
WE HAVE HAD REALLY GOOD PEOPLE
WHO HAVE NOT MADE IT THROUGH
THIS PROCESS.
I REMEMBER SO WELL THE ICONIC
FIGURE TED SORNSEN NAMED CHIEF
AND IT WAS DEAD AFTER A TIME.
TED SORENSON WENT ON TO GREAT
THINGS, BUT THIS WILL BE ALWAYS
BE A TOUGH CHAPTER IN HIS LIFE.
>> YOU SAID THE SENATE WAS
COMFORTABLE WITH JOHN KERRY.
I THINK IN A WAY THE SENATE
WOULD HAVE BEEN MORE COMFORTABLE
WITH SUSAN RICE.
IT IS NOT THAT HE DOESN'T LIKE
JOHN KERRY.
JOHN KERRY HELPED HIM OUT DURING
DEBATES.
HE'S KNOWN HIM FOR A LONG TIME.
SUSAN RICE IS A DEAR OLD FRIEND
AND THERE IS ANOTHER ISSUE HERE
WHICH IS THE QUESTION OF
DIVERSITY.
BECAUSE IT SORT OF ALL STACKS UP
AS WE THINK IT'S GOING, IT LOOKS
LIKE THE TOP FOUR CABINET POSTS
CAN NOW POTENTIALLY BE FILLED BY
MEN AND I'M SURE THAT THAT'S
SOMETHING THAT THE WHITE HOUSE
REALLY IS THINKING ABOUT.
>> THIS TEAM THAT LOOKS TO BE
FALLING INTO PLACE, TALKING
ABOUT REPUBLICANS FOR DEFENSE,
TO REPLACE PANETTA, DOES IT SEEM
LIKE A TEAM THAT CAN MAKE IT
THROUGH CONFIRMATION INTO SENATE
IF JOHN KERRY IS ALSO INVOLVED?
>> IT DOES.
UNLESS THERE IS SOMETHING WE
DON'T KNOW ABOUT.
FOR EXAMPLE, TOM DASCHLE,
CERTAINLY VERY IMPORTANT MEMBER
OF THE CLUB, THE SENATE CLUB.
HE DIDN'T MAKE IT THROUGH
BECAUSE THERE WAS A SURPRISE
ISSUE WITH HIS TAX RETURNS FOUR
YEARS AGO.
WITH REGARD IT JOHN KERRY, EVEN
THE REPUBLICAN LEADER LATE TODAY
SAID KIND WORDS ABOUT HIM.
IT IS VIRTUALLY SURE THAT HE IS
GOING TO GET THROUGH THE SENATE
BECAUSE HE HAS BEEN VETTED IN
MANY WAYS BECAUSE HE WAS THE
PRESIDENTIAL CAN CANDIDATE.
YOU KNOW, YOU DON'T GET MORE
VETTED THAN THAT.
WITH REGARD IT CHUCK HAGEL, SAME
THING.
HE IS SOMEBODY WHO DIDN'T HAVE
THE CLOSEST RELATIONSHIPS HERE
BUT THE FACT THAT IT WOULD BE A
BIPARTISAN PICK BECAUSE HE IS A
REPUBLICAN WOULD GO A LONG WAY
LIKELY.
IT DOES LOOK LIKE IT IS SHAPING
UP.
ONE THING ABOUT SUSAN VETTING
HERE ON CAPITOL HILL, AND IT IS
NATIONAL SECURITY ADVISER.
THAT'S MORE INHERENTLY
POLITICAL, A JOB INSIDE THE
WHITE HOUSE AND MORE IMPORTANTLY
SHE WOULDN'T NEED SENATE
CONFIRMATION.
>> THANKS VERY MUCH.
>>> POLITICS AND HIGH STAKES.
WHEN IT COMES TO THE TAXES YOU
PAY, SIZE OF THE GOVERNMENT AND
THE ECONOMY THAT WORKS.
JOHN BOEHNER IS BACK AT IT,
MEETING TONIGHT, TRYING IT ONCE
AGAIN TO REACH A DEAL ON THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
THE QUESTION IS, WILL IT BE ANY
DIFFERENT THIS TIME.
>> HEY ANDERSON, TONIGHT THE TWO
MEN MET FOR 50 MINUTES THE OVAL
OFFICE AS THEY STRUGGLED IT FIND
WAY OUT OF STALEMATE.
SO FAR, NO WORD OF THE BREAK
THROUGH.
BOTH AIDES DESCRIBE THE
CONVERSATION AS FRANK AND WE'RE
TOLD THAT LINES OF COMMUNICATION
REMAIN OPEN.
NOW, THAT IS POLITICAL SPEAK AND
I WILL TRANSLATE IT FOR YOU.
FRANK, THAT GENERALLY MEANS THAT
CONVERSATION WAS SOMEWHAT TENSE
OF LINES OF COMMUNICATION
REMAINS OPEN.
THAT MEANS THAT THE TWO MENS'
STAFF WILL CONTINUE TALKING AND
THERE IS NO CURRENT PLAN FOR THE
TWO MEN, THE PRESIDENT AND
SPEAKER BOEHNER, TO HAVE A
FOLLOW-UP MEETING.
>> AFTER YET AND SPEAKER BOEHNER
DOES PLAN IT RETURN HOME TO OHIO
TOMORROW.
NOW THAT'S A CHALLENGE BECAUSE
FOR A DEAL TO COME TOGETHER,
BECAUSE THEY ARE RUNNING OUT OF
TIME.
THEY ARE ALL ABOUT OUT OF TIME
TO GET A DEAL DONE BEFORE THE
CHRISTMAS DEADLINE AND NEXT TO
OUT OF TIME TO GET ONE DONE
BEFORE THE NEW YEAR.
ANDERSON?
>> JESSICA, THANKS VERY MUCH.
LET US KNOW WHAT YOU THINK.
CAN YOU FOLLOW ME ON TWITTER
RIGHT NOW.
I WILL BE TWEETING TONIGHT.
>>> NEXT, OUTBREAK OF DEADLY
DISEASE AND ALLEGATIONS OF WHAT
OFFICIALS AT ONE HOSPITAL KNEW
ABOUT THE RISK LONG BEFORE
ANYONE DIED.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS STEVE.
HE LOVES RISK.
BUT WHETHER
HE'S CLIMBING EVEREST,
SCUBA DIVING THE
GREAT BARRIER REEF WITH SHARKS,
OR JUMPING INTO THE MARKET,
HE GOES WITH PEOPLE HE TRUSTS,
WHICH IS WHY HE TRADES
WITH A COMPANY
THAT DOESN'T NICKEL AND DIME
HIM WITH HIDDEN FEES.
SO HE CAN WORRY
ABOUT OTHER THINGS,
LIKE WHAT THE MARKET IS DOING
AND BEING READY,
NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENS,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE,
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
BUT PROVEN TECHNOLOGIES
ALLOW NATURAL GAS PRODUCERS
TO SUPPLY AFFORDABLE,
CLEANER ENERGY,
WHILE PROTECTING
OUR ENVIRONMENT.
ACROSS AMERICA, THESE
TECHNOLOGIES PROTECT AIR -
BY MONITORING AIR QUALITY
AND REDUCING EMISSIONS...
...PROTECT WATER -
THROUGH CONSERVATION
AND SELF-CONTAINED
RECYCLING SYSTEMS...
... AND PROTECT LAND -
BY REDUCING OUR FOOTPRINT
AND RESPECTING WILDLIFE.
AMERICA'S NATURAL GAS...
DOMESTIC, ABUNDANT, CLEAN
ENERGY TO POWER OUR LIVES...
THAT'S SMARTER POWER TODAY.
♪ HARK HOW THE BELLS,
SWEET SILVER BELLS ♪
♪ ALL SEEM TO SAY
THROW CARE AWAY ♪
♪ FROM EVERYWHERE,
FILLING THE AIR ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
CHEX PARTY MIX.
EASY 15-MINUTE
HOMEMADE RECIPES
YOU JUST POP IN A MICROWAVE.
LIKE CARAMEL CHOCOLATE
DRIZZLES.
HAPPIER HOLIDAYS.
CHEX PARTY MIX.
have led to an increase intands
clinical depression.
Drug and alcohol abuse is up.
And those dealing with grief
don't have access to the
professional help they need.
When you see these issues, do
you want to walk away or
step up?
With a degree in the field of
Counseling or Psychology from
Capella University, you'll have
the knowledge to make
a difference in the lives of
others.
Let's get started at
CAPELLA.EDU
>>> KEEPING THEM HONEST NOW,
LOOKING FOR FACTS TONIGHT, NOT
OFFERING OPINIONS OR PLAYING
FAVORITES.
OUR GOAL TONIGHT IS JUST REAL
REPORTING, AS IT IS EVERY NIGHT,
FINDING THE TRUTH AND CALLING
OUT HYPOCRISY.
TONIGHT THE STAKES ARE LIFE AND
DEATH.
EVERY YEAR MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
THAT PUT THEIR LIVES ON THE LINE
FOR OUR COUNTRY PUT THEMSELVES
IN HOSPITALS.
TENS OF MILLIONS GET TREATMENT
IN VIRGINIA CLINICS AND DESERVE
THE BEST CARE POSSIBLE.
CERTAINLY NONE SHOULD EXPECT A
TRIP TO THE HOSPITAL MIGHT MAKE
THEM SICK OR KILL THEM.
ONE PITTSBURGH AREA FAMILY SAID
THAT IS EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED TO
THEIR DAD AND THERE COULD BE
MORE CASES LIKE HIS.
HE WAS TREATED IN PITTSBURGH'S
VA SYSTEM, ONE OF THE MOST
HIGHLY REGARDED IN THE NATION
AND MAY HAVE DIED BECAUSE OF
WHAT HE CAUGHT THERE,
LEGIONNAIRE'S DISEASE, AN
INFECTION THAT SPREADS IN
CONTAMINATED WATER SUPPLIES.
WHAT MAKES THIS STORY EVEN MORE
TROUBLING IS THE EVIDENCE CNN
HAS UNCOVERED.
IT SHOWS THAT HOSPITAL OFFICIALS
KNEW ABOUT THE PROBLEM AND YET
APPARENTLY THEY FAILED TO FIX
IT.
SINCE JANUARY OF LAST YEAR, LAST
YEAR, THERE HAVE BEEN AT LEAST
FIVE CASES DIRECTLY TRACEABLE TO
THE VA HOSPITAL SYSTEM IN
PITTSBURGH, BUT ONLY LAST MONTH
DID THE VA ADMIT THEY HAD A
PROBLEM WITH THEIR WATER SUPPLY.
THEY SAID SO IN A NEWS RELEASE
AND ISSUED TWO MORE, INCLUDING
ONE THAT SAID THE PROBLEM HAS
BEEN SOLVED.
APART FROM NEWS RELEASES,
THOUGH, THEY'RE SIMPLY NOT
TALKING.
HOWEVER, DREW GRIFFIN IS
INVESTIGATING.
>> HE FIRMLY BELIEVED THAT THE
VA WAS GOING TO GIVE HIM THE
BEST CARE THEY COULD POSSIBLY
GIVE HIM.
>> KNOWING WHAT YOU KNOW NOW,
DID THE VA GIVE HIM THE BEST
CARE POSSIBLE?
>> NO.
NO, THEY DIDN'T.
I MEAN I CAN SAY THERE WAS
STRONG NEGLIGENCE ON THE VA'S
PART.
>> BOB NICHOLAS IS TALKING ABOUT
HIS FATHER, BILL.
A WORLD WAR II NAVY HERO, WHO
WOULD DROP INTO HOSTILE WATERS
TO SAVE DOWNED NAVY PILOTS.
BUT BILL NICHOLAS DIED THE DAY
AFTER THANKSGIVING FROM HEART
FAILURE AND LEGIONNAIRE'S
DISEASE.
HE CONTRACTED IT FROM USING THE
WATER AT THE VA, WHICH WAS
CONTAMINATED WITH HIGH LEVELS OF
A BACTERIA, THE CAUSE OF
LEGIONNAIRE'S DISEASE.
TWO OTHER FAMILIES ARE WONDERING
WHETHER THEIR VETERANS
CONTRACTED THE LEGIONNAIRE'S
DISEASE THAT KILLED THEM FROM
THIS SAME PITTSBURGH VA.
CNN HAS NOW LEARNED THAT
HOSPITAL OFFICIALS KNEW THEY HAD
A PROBLEM WITH THE WATER SYSTEM
AS FAR BACK AS DECEMBER OF LAST
YEAR, BUT CHOSE NOT TO REVEAL
ANY OF THAT PUBLICLY UNTIL A
MONTH AGO.
>> BEING A VETERAN MYSELF, I'M
SHOCKED AND APPALLED THAT THE VA
WOULD PUT THEIR VETERANS IN THAT
TYPE OF SITUATION.
>> RECORDS OBTAINED BY CNN SHOW
THAT OVER THE PAST YEAR, THE
AMOUNT OF DISINFECTANT IN THE
VA'S WATER WAS LESS THAN THE
AMOUNT NEEDED TO PREVENT THE
BACTERIA FROM REACHING DANGEROUS
LEVELS, AND INTERNAL RECORDS
FROM A WATER QUALITY COMPANY
CALLED LIQUITECH SHOW THAT IN
DECEMBER OF 2011, AN INSPECTION
SHOW THEY HAVE LEGIONELA,
SYSTEMS NOT BEING PROPERLY
MAINTAINED.
FIVE MONTHS LATER THE PROBLEMS
CONTINUED.
OBVIOUS EVIDENCE THAT THE
SYSTEMS HAD NOT BEEN PROPERLY,
REGULARLY MAINTAINED.
LIQUITECH IS THE CONTRACTOR WHO
INSTALLED THE VA'S WATER SYSTEM,
AND A SYSTEM LIKE IT IN HUNDREDS
OF OTHER HOSPITALS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY.
HE SAYS IT IS INEXPLICABLE THAT
THE VA HOSPITAL IN PITTSBURGH
KNEW IT HAD A PROBLEM, WAS
WARNED ABOUT IT AND DID NOT FIX
IT.
>> THEY WERE NOT CLEANING THE
FLOW CELLS, NOT DOING THE
MONITORING, NOT DOING THE THINGS
NECESSARY FOR THE EFFICACY OF
THE SYSTEM.
>> DID YOU TELL THE HOSPITAL?
>> YES, WE DID.
YES, WE DID.
WE TOLD THEM -- WE ACTUALLY HAD
TWO AUDITS AND TOLD THEM TWICE
THAT THEY WERE DEFICIENT IN
THEIR MAINTENANCE.
>> WHAT IS SO FRUSTRATING IS IF
THE SYSTEM HAD JUST BEEN
MAINTAINED, IF THE HOSPITAL HAD
JUST LISTENED AND MADE SIMPLE
ADJUSTMENTS, HE SAYS HE BELIEVES
LIVES COULD HAVE BEEN SAVED.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
ABSOLUTELY.
>> 100%?
>> 100%.
>> AS IS DONE IN ALL THE OTHER
HOSPITALS THAT YOU SERVICE?
>> YES.
>> THIS OUTBREAK WAS ABSOLUTELY
PREVENTIBLE.
>> DR. JANET STOUT WITH HER
COLLEAGUE, DR. VICTOR YU WORKED
FOR MORE THAN 20 YEARS AT THIS
SAME PITTSBURGH VA HOSPITAL
RESEARCHING LEGIONNAIRE'S
DISEASE.
THEY WERE PIONEERS IN THE FIELD,
DEVELOPING THE COPPER SILVER
IONIZATION FILTRATION SYSTEM
WHICH IS STILL BEING USED AS
PITTSBURGH'S VA AND IN HOSPITALS
NATIONWIDE.
SIX YEARS AGO IN A CONTROVERSIAL
MOVE, THE DOCTORS AND THEIR
LEGIONELLA RESEARCH LAB WERE
TOLD BY THE VA THAT THEIR
SERVICES WERE NOT PRODUCTIVE AND
A DRAIN ON CLINICAL RESOURCES.
THE DOCTORS SAY FOR A DECADE
BEFORE THEY LEFT, NOT A SINGLE
PATIENT GOT LEGIONNAIRE'S FROM
THE HOSPITAL'S WATER.
SHE SAYS IF SHE WERE STILL THERE
MONITORING THE WATER, THIS
ENTIRE TRAGEDY WOULD HAVE BEEN
PREVENTED WITH THE TURN OF A
KNOB.
>> SO THIS IS NOT, AS THEY SAY,
ROCKET SCIENCE.
THIS IS STRAIGHTFORWARD.
>> SO WHAT WENT WRONG?
OUR CALLS AND E-MAILS TO THE VA
WENT UNANSWERED, SO KEEPING THEM
HONEST, WE WENT TO THE UNITED
STATES VETERANS ADMINISTRATION
HOSPITAL IN PITTSBURGH IN HOPES
OF GETTING ANSWERS.
WE WERE MET BY FOUR ARMED
FEDERAL OFFICERS.
>> HEY, HOW ARE YOU?
DREW GRIFFIN WITH CNN.
>> WE'RE WITH THE VA POLICE.
>> YES, SIR.
>> THIS HAS NOT BEEN APPROVED BY
OUR PUBLIC AFFAIRS OFFICE.
I CANNOT ALLOW YOU ON THE
PROPERTY.
>> I'M CALLING PUBLIC AFFAIRS
RIGHT NOW.
>> OKAY.
>> WOULD YOU YOU LIKE TO CALL
THEM.
>> I CAN'T TECHNICALLY CALL
WOULD YOU LIKE TO TAKE THE
CAMERAS BACK ACROSS THE STREET?
>> HOLD ON, I'M ON THE PHONE
WITH THEM.
>> AFTER YET REACHING JUST A
MESSAGE MACHINE, THE OFFICER
TOLD US TO LEAVE.
>> WHO TOLD YOU TO KICK US OFF
OF HERE?
>> IT'S OUR POLICY ACTUALLY.
>> YOUR POLICY?
WE CAN'T STAND ON UNITED STATES
GOVERNMENT LAND WITH A CAMERA?
>> WITHOUT A LEGITIMATE PURPOSE
FOR BEING HERE.
>> I'M TRYING TO FIND OUT WHY
THESE PATIENTS DIED.
>> AND BEING NEWS MEDIA WHILE
RECORDING, I'M GOING TO HAVE TO
ASK YOU TO LEAVE UNTIL IT'S
APPROVED BY OUR PUBLIC AFFAIRS
OFFICE.
>> INSTEAD OF ANSWERING OUR
QUESTIONS, THE VA SPOKESPERSON
HAS RELEASED THREE MEDIA
ADVISORIES, THE LAST ONE ON THE
DAY WE VISITED READ IN A VOICE
MAIL.
>> VA IS COMMITTED TO PROVIDING
SAFE FACILITIES AND QUALITY CARE
FOR VETERANS.
>> THE ADVISORY GOES ON TO SAY
THAT AN INVESTIGATION IS UNDER
WAY AND THAT --
>> TESTING RESULTS INDICATE THE
REMEDIATION AT PITTSBURGH VA
MEDICAL CENTER UNIVERSITY DRIVE
HAS BEEN SUCCESSFUL.
>> BILL NICHOLAS' FLAG STILL
FLIES ON THE FRONT LAWN THAT HE
MOWED HIMSELF.
HE WOULD HAVE TURNED 88 THIS
PAST WEEKEND.
INSTEAD OF CELEBRATING HIS
BIRTHDAY, HIS FAMILY HELD A
MEMORIAL SERVICE.
>> THEY SHOULD HAVE THE BEST AND
UTMOST CARE THAT ANYBODY ELSE,
EVEN BETTER THAN A NORMAL
CIVILIAN.
THEY FOUGHT FOR THEIR COUNTRY,
THEY GO TO BATTLE, YOU KNOW,
THEY LOVE THEIR COUNTRY AND
WHERE DO THEY GO?
THEY GO TO A HOSPITAL AND THEY
BASICALLY DIE IN THERE.
>> ANDERSON, LET ME TELL YOU
JUST A LITTLE BIT MORE ABOUT
BILL NICHOLAS.
THIS GUY, DRAFTED AT 17 YEARS
OLD INTO THE U.S. NAVY.
HE WOULD DRIVE 30 MILES OUT OF
HIS WAY PAST TWO OTHER HOSPITALS
JUST TO GO TO THE VA, BECAUSE HE
THOUGHT HE WOULD GET BETTER CARE
THERE AS A VETERAN, WHICH IS WHY
HIS SONS REALLY FEEL LET DOWN BY
THIS.
>> WE KNOW THREE POSSIBLE DEATHS
DUE TO THIS LEGIONELLA AT THE
HOSPITAL.
BUT THERE COULD BE MORE DEATHS,
RIGHT?
>> CERTAINLY, ALL OF THE
INFORMATION ONES THIS CASES, 29
CASES, IS COMING FROM THE
HOSPITAL.
THIS HAS BEEN GOING ON FOR A
YEAR NOW, ANDERSON.
I THINK A LOT OF HEALTH CARE
PROFESSIONALS, A LOT OF
FAMILIES, QUITE FRANKLY, ARE
GOING TO LOOK BACK OVER THIS
YEAR, LOOK BACK AT THE FAMILY
MEMBERS THEY MAY HAVE LOST, AND
BEGIN ASKING QUESTIONS ABOUT
WHAT THIS WAS THAT KILLED THEIR
LOVED ONE.
COULD IT HAVE BEEN THIS
LEGIONNAIRE'S DISEASE.
>> AND WHO BESIDES US ARE TRYING
TO GET ANSWERS ON THIS?
IS THE VA STILL REFUSING TO TALK
TO YOU?
>> YEAH, THEY WILL NOT COME OUT.
AS YOU SAW IN THAT PIECE, THEY
WON'T TALK TO US AT ALL.
THE VA IN PITTSBURGH REFERRED US
TO THE WASHINGTON PR DIVISION
WHO SENT US RIGHT BACK TO
PITTSBURGH.
IT'S BEEN A MESS.
BUT THE CENTERS FOR DISEASE
CONTROL AND PREVENTION, THEY DID
SEND A TEAM THERE IN NOVEMBER TO
INVESTIGATE THIS.
WE'RE TOLD THAT THE
INVESTIGATION, THE RESULTS FROM
THE CDC WILL GO TO THE VA IN THE
COMING WEEKS.
WE'RE NOT SURE IF THAT'S GOING
TO BE RELEASED TO THE PUBLIC.
>> I STILL CAN'T UNDERSTAND WHY
THE VA DID NOTHING WHEN THEY
KNEW THEY HAD A PROBLEM?
>> ACTUALLY, ANDERSON, WE FOUND
OUT THAT ABOUT SIX MONTHS AGO
THE VA DID BRING IN A CONSULTANT
WHO MADE RECOMMENDATIONS ON HOW
TO FIX THE WATER, BUT THE VA DID
NOT TELL THAT CONSULTANT THAT
THEY HAD LEGIONNAIRE'S CASES AT
THE HOSPITAL.
IF THEY HAD TOLD THE CONSULTANTS
THAT THERE WOULD HAVE BEEN
DIFFERENT RECOMMENDATIONS.
THE VA WOULD HAVE BEEN TOLD TO
HANDLE IT DIFFERENTLY.
WE JUST DON'T KNOW WHY, BECAUSE
THE VA WON'T TALK TO US.
>> THAT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
DREW, APPRECIATE IT, THANKS.
>>> A CNN EXCLUSIVE AHEAD.
A TRULY BREATH-TAKING DISPLAY OF
COURAGE BY A SYRIAN TEENAGER.
HE RISKED HIS LIFE TO SAVE A
STRANGER, A WOMAN WHO WAS HIT BY
A SNIPER.
THAT'S HIM CRAWLING ALONG THE
GROUND TRYING TO RESCUE THIS
LADY.
ARWA DAMON'S REPORT IS NEXT.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
HOW THEY'LL LIVE TOMORROW.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
A Hybrid? Most are
just no fun to drive.
Now, here's one that will
make you feel alive.
Meet the five-passenger
Ford C-MAX Hybrid.
C-MAX says ha.
C-MAX says wheeee.
Which is what you get,
don't you see?
Cause C-MAX has lots more
horsepower than Prius v,
a hybrid that C-MAX
also bests in MPG.
Say hi to the all-new 47
combined MPG C-MAX Hybrid.
>>> TWO CHILDREN KILLED, A
BROTHER AND SISTER, JUST 3 AND 5
YEARS OLD.
EACH STABBED MORE THAN A DOZEN
TIMES.
THEIR KILLER, THEIR OWN FATHER,
WHO WAS A DOCTOR.
HE'S NOW A FREE MAN.
WE'LL TELL YOU WHY COMING UP.
>>> TONIGHT A 360 EXCLUSIVE FROM
SYRIA.
AN EXTRAORDINARY DISPLAY OF
BRAVERY UNDER A SNIPER'S ALLEY.
A TEENAGE BOY, WHO RISKED HIS
LIFE, SAYS HE'S NO HERO, THAT HE
DID WHAT COUNTLESS OTHERS DO
EVERY DAY.
WE'RE GOING TO SHOW YOU THAT IN
A MOMENT.
>>> FIRST, NEW SIGNS THAT DEFEAT
COULD BE NEAR FOR AL ASSAD'S
REGIME.
HE IS LOSING CONTROL OF HIS
COUNTRY AND ADMITTED THE
OPPOSITION COULD WIN.
NATO'S LEADER SAID THE REGIME IS
APPROACHING COLLAPSE.
THEIR COMMENTS CAME AS
OPPOSITION GROUPS SEIZED A
MILITARY BASE NEAR DAMASCUS.
SYRIAN STATE TELEVISION SAID AT
LEAST TWO DOZEN CIVILIANS WERE
KILLED IN TWO CAR BOMBINGS
OUTSIDE OF DAMASCUS.
SEVEN CHILDREN WERE SAID TO BE
AMONG THOSE KILLED IN THIS
BLAST.
IN A NEARBY TOWN, EIGHT PEOPLE,
MOSTLY WOMEN AND CHILDREN, WERE
REPORTED KILLED IN THIS BOMBING
ACCORDING TO STATE TELEVISION.
ASSAD SHOWS NO OUTWARD SIGNS OF
BACKING DOWN AND IN HOT SPOTS
CIVILIANS ARE STILL DYING IN THE
CROSSFIRE.
NOW THAT ACT OF INCREDIBLE
COURAGE THAT WAS CAUGHT ON TAPE.
HERE IS ARWA DAMON'S EXCLUSIVE
REPORT.
>> Reporter: A FIGHTER SLITHERS
ACROSS THE STREET, HIS BODY
COVERED.
YARDS AWAY A WOMAN LIES
MOTIONLESS.
SHE'S BEEN SHOT BY A SNIPER.
HER RESCUER IS NOT A RELATIVE,
NOR A NEIGHBOR.
HE'S NEVER MET HER.
ABDULLAH FAHAN IS JUST 17.
HE KNEW HE HAD TO SAVE THE WOMAN
OR DIE TRYING.
WHEN WE MET HIM LATER, HE TELLS
US --
[ SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE ]
>> Reporter: -- WE HAD A FEELING
THAT SHE WAS STILL ALIVE.
WE WANTED TO SAVE HER, TO GET
HER TO A HOSPITAL.
AS HE CRAWLS CLOSER, HE CAN SEE
HER HAND.
HER FINGERS SHAKING.
COVER HIM, COVER HIM, SOMEONE
SHOUTS.
OTHER FIGHTERS LAY DOWN COVER
FIRE.
ABDULLAH QUICKLY TIES THE HOSE
TO HER LEGS, BUT HE'S UNABLE TO
RETREAT.
>> Reporter: I SAID TO MYSELF,
IF I DIE, IT'S GOD'S WILL THAT I
DIE NEXT TO THIS WOMAN, HE TELLS
US.
FINALLY, HE MAKES A RUN FOR IT,
AND THE REBELS DRAG THE WOMAN
BACK.
[ GUNFIRE ]
>> Reporter: THE WOMAN AND HER
SON WERE WALKING RIGHT DOWN THE
STREET THERE.
REBEL FIGHTERS SHOUTED AT THEM
TO STAY AWAY, BUT IT WAS TOO
LATE.
ALEPPO IS CRISSCROSSED WITH
SIMILAR SNIPER ALLEYS.
SOME ARE KNOWN, BUT OTHERS DO
NOT REVEAL THEMSELVES UNTIL THE
FIRST SHOT HAS BEEN FIRED.
DESPITE ABDULLAH'S EFFORTS, THE
WOMAN DIES.
HER SON UTTERLY DISTRAUGHT.
[ SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE ]
>> Reporter: DON'T DIE NOW,
DON'T DIE TODAY, HE PLEADS.
ANSWER ME, MOM, ANSWER ME.
SHE'S NOT DEAD, SHE'S NOT DEAD,
HE SAYS, AS HE COLLAPSES.
ABDULLAH IS LEFT WONDERING
WHETHER HER LIFE COULD HAVE BEEN
SAVED IF HE'D REACHED HER
SOONER.
UNTIL RECENTLY HE WORKED AS A
BAKERY.
NOW LIKE THOUSANDS OF YOUNG
SYRIANS, HE PUTS HIS LIFE ON THE
LINE.
I AM NOT A HERO, I AM JUST LIKE
ANYONE ELSE, HE TELLS US.
AND WE'RE LEFT TO WONDER, HOW
MANY SIMILAR ACTS OF COURAGE GO
UNRECORDED EVERY DAY IN SYRIA,
AND HOW MANY INNOCENTS ARE LOST?
ARWA DAMON, CNN, ALEPPO.
>> ARWA DAMON REPORTING.
>>> THERE'S A LOT MORE HAPPENING
TONIGHT.
HERE IS THE 360 BULLETIN.
>>> THE TALIBAN HAS TAKEN CREDIT
FOR A SUICIDE BOMBING IN
AFGHANISTAN THAT KILLED AT LEAST
THREE PEOPLE, INCLUDING ONE
AMERICAN.
THE ATTACK HAPPENED NEAR
KANDAHAR'S AIR FIELD JUST HOURS
AFTER U.S. DEFENSE SECRETARY
LEON PANETTA LEFT THE CITY.
>>> FOR THE FIRST TIME WE'RE
GETTING A LOOK AT NORTH KOREA'S
FIRST APPARENT SUCCESSFUL LAUNCH
OF A LONG-RANGE MISSILE,
COURTESY OF THE STATE-RUN NEWS
AGENCY.
THE COUNTRY'S LEADER CELEBRATED
WITH SOLDIERS.
>>> THE REMAINS OF MUSIC STAR
JENNI RIVERA HAVE BEEN
IDENTIFIED AND RETURNED TO HER
FAMILY.
RIVERA AND SIX OTHERS ARE
BELIEVED TO HAVE DIED IN
SUNDAY'S PLANE CRASH IN MEXICO.
THE CAUSE OF THE CRASH IS UNDER
INVESTIGATION.
>>> AND TWO MEN ARRESTED IN A
MURDER-FOR-HIRE PLOT WERE
PLANNING ON CASTRATING AND
KILLING JUSTIN BIEBER, THAT'S
ACCORDING TO POLICE IN NEW
MEXICO AND VERMONT.
THE SUSPECTS, A CONVICTED FELON
AND HIS 23-YEAR-OLD NEPHEW, WERE
ALLEGEDLY HIRED BY AN INMATE IN
NEW MEXICO INFATUATED WITH THE
POP MUSIC STAR.
ANDERSON?
>> THANKS.
MUCH MORE AHEAD, INCLUDING A
MOTHER'S GRIEF AND OUTRAGE.
HER YOUNG SON AND DAUGHTER WERE
VICIOUSLY STABBED TO DEATH BY
THEIR OWN FATHER.
HE CONFESSED, BUT NOW HE'S FREE.
COMING UP, HIS EX-WIFE'S FIGHT
TO MAKE SURE NO OTHER FAMILY
SUFFERS WHAT SHE HAS ENDURED.
of Washington about the future
of Medicare and Social Security.
ANNCR: But you deserve straight
talk about the options on the...
table and what they mean for you
and your family.
ANCR: AARP is cutting through
all the political spin.
Because for our 37 million
members, only one word counts.
Get the facts at earnedasay.org.
Let's keep Medicare...
and Social Security strong for
generations to come.
THOSE LITTLE THINGS
FOR YOU, LIFE'S ABOUT HER.
BUT YOUR ERECTILE DYSFUNCTION -
THAT COULD BE A
QUESTION OF BLOOD FLOW.
CIALIS TADALAFIL
FOR DAILY USE
HELPS YOU
BE READY
ANYTIME THE
MOMENT'S RIGHT.
YOU CAN BE
MORE CONFIDENT
IN YOUR ABILITY TO BE READY.
AND THE SAME CIALIS
IS THE ONLY DAILY
ED TABLET APPROVED TO TREAT
ED AND SYMPTOMS OF BPH,
LIKE NEEDING TO GO
FREQUENTLY OR URGENTLY.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ALL YOUR MEDICAL
CONDITIONS AND MEDICATIONS,
AND ASK IF YOUR HEART IS HEALTHY
ENOUGH FOR SEXUAL ACTIVITY.
DO NOT TAKE CIALIS IF YOU TAKE
NITRATES FOR CHEST PAIN,
AS THIS MAY CAUSE AN UNSAFE
DROP IN BLOOD PRESSURE.
DO NOT DRINK ALCOHOL
IN EXCESS WITH CIALIS.
SIDE EFFECTS MAY INCLUDE
HEADACHE, UPSET STOMACH,
DELAYED BACKACHE OR MUSCLE ACHE.
TO AVOID LONG-TERM INJURY,
SEEK IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
FOR AN ERECTION LASTING
MORE THAN FOUR HOURS.
IF YOU HAVE ANY SUDDEN DECREASE
OR LOSS IN HEARING OR VISION,
OR IF YOU HAVE ANY ALLERGIC
REACTIONS SUCH AS RASH, HIVES,
SWELLING OF THE LIPS,
TONGUE OR THROAT,
OR DIFFICULTY BREATHING
OR SWALLOWING,
STOP TAKING CIALIS AND GET
MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY.
ASK YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT
CIALIS FOR DAILY USE
AND A 30-TABLET FREE TRIAL.
>>> HER DEATH SHOCKED THE WORLD,
NOW BRITISH POLICE ARE RELEASING
NEW INFORMATION ABOUT THE NURSE
WHO TOOK HER OWN LIFE AFTER
TRANSFERRING A CALL TO THE WARD
TREATING PRINCESS CATHERINE.
WHAT THEY'RE SAYING ABOUT THE
CIRCUMSTANCES SURROUNDING HER
DEATH NEXT.
>>> A MOTHER WHOSE YOUNG
CHILDREN WERE VICIOUSLY STABBED
TO DEATH IS REELING TONIGHT.
THEIR KILLER IS BACK ON THE
STREETS.
HE WAS RELEASED FROM A MENTAL
HEALTH FACILITY JUST YESTERDAY.
THE CASE IS AS CONTROVERSIAL AS
IT IS HORRIFYING.
5-YEAR-OLD OLIVIER AND HIS
3-YEAR-OLD SISTER WERE STABBED
TO DEATH IN THEIR OWN BEDS.
EACH CHILD HAD OVER A DOZEN
WOUNDS.
AS HORRIBLE AS THOSE FACTS ALONE
ARE, THE REST IS WORSE.
THEIR FATHER, A PHYSICIAN, IS
THE ONE WHO KILLED THEM AND HE
CONFESSED.
BUT A CANADIAN JURY RULED THAT
HE WASN'T CRIMINALLY RESPONSIBLE
BECAUSE OF HIS MENTAL STATE AT
THE TIME.
INSTEAD OF PRISON, HE WAS SENT
TO A MENTAL HEALTH FACILITY.
NOW HE'S FREE AND HE HAS NO
CRIMINAL RECORD.
HIS EX-WIFE, WHO'S ALSO A
DOCTOR, FOUGHT HARD TO KEEP THAT
FROM HAPPENING.
PAULA NEWTON HAS MORE.
>> Reporter: AS ISABEL GASTON
POURS OVER HER OWN CHILDREN'S
AUTOPSY REPORTS, SHE WISHES SHE
HAD NO IDEA WHAT THEY MEANT.
BUT AS A PHYSICIAN AND A
CORONER, SHE KNOWS IT'S TRUE.
HER CHILDREN SUFFERED LONG,
GRUESOME DEATHS.
>> I KNEW THAT IT WAS NOT A
SHORT DEATH.
MY LITTLE BOY RECEIVED 20 -- 20
STABS OF A KNIFE.
HE HAD SEVEN MARKS OF DEFENSE.
HE HAD NO WOUND THAT WAS THE ONE
THAT GAVE HIM DEATH.
>> THERE WAS NO MERCY?
>> NO.
MY LITTLE GIRL HAD 19 WOUNDS.
MAYBE SHE WAS LUCKIER BECAUSE
SHE HAD ONE THAT WAS MORE MORTAL
THAN THE OTHER, BUT SHE FELT THE
19 SHOTS FOR SURE.
>> Reporter: BUT THIS WAS NO
RANDOM ACT OF VIOLENCE.
THE KNIFE WAS WIELDED BY THE
CHILDREN'S FATHER AND GASTON'S
EX-HUSBAND, CARDIOLOGIST DR. GUY
TURCOTTE.
>> TO KNOW THAT MY CHILDREN
FACED THE PERSON THAT THEY
SHOULD TRUST THE MOST AND THEY
WERE LEFT BY THEMSELF TO DIE, NO
ONE HOLDING THEIR HAND, I
STRUGGLE, OKAY.
I STRUGGLE ALL THE DAY, EVERY
DAY OF MY LIFE, AND UNTIL I DIE
I WILL STRUGGLE.
>> THE DOCTOR ADMITS HE KILLED
HIS CHILDREN IN 2009, AND YET
NOW HE IS A FREE MAN, EVEN
POSSIBLY FREE TO PRACTICE
MEDICINE AGAIN.
IN 2010 A CANADIAN JURY FAILED
TO CONVICT HIM OF THE MURDERS,
FINDING HIM NOT CRIMINALLY
RESPONSIBLE DUE TO MENTAL
ILLNESS.
HE KILLED HIS CHILDREN ON WHAT
WAS SUPPOSED TO BE A FAMILY
MOVIE NIGHT.
THIS SURVEILLANCE VIDEO SHOWS
HIM RENTING VIDEOS WITH HIS
CHILDREN JUST HOURS BEFORE HE
BRUTALLY STABBED THEM IN HIS
BED.
THESE WERE TROUBLING TIMES FOR
THE DOCTOR.
HE WAS SEPARATED FROM HIS WIFE.
SHE HAD LEFT HIM FOR ANOTHER
MAN.
HE SAID HE SUFFERED A BLACKOUT
AND DOES NOT REMEMBER STABBING
THE CHILDREN.
THE VERDICT IS BEING APPEALED.
>> DO YOU BELIEVE HE WAS
MENTALLY INSANE WHEN HE
COMMITTED THE MURDERS, AND DO
YOU BELIEVE HE'S MENTALLY INSANE
NOW?
>> NO, NO.
>> WHY?
>> WHY SHOULD I, THAT I DON'T
ACCEPT HE IS MENTALLY ILL, WHEN
I LOOK AT THE FACTS, OKAY.
WE HAVE A PERSON THAT'S A
CARDIOLOGIST THAT HAS NEVER HAD
A PSYCHIATRIC INCIDENT, NEVER,
NOT AT ALL.
>> THE JURY BELIEVED THE
TESTIMONY OF TWO PSYCHIATRISTS
PRESENTED BY THE DEFENSE.
THEY TESTIFIED THAT THE DOCTOR
COULD NOT HAVE KNOWN WHAT HE WAS
DOING WHEN HE REPEATEDLY STABBED
5-YEAR-OLD OLIVIER AND
3-YEAR-OLD ANN-SOPHIE.
>> I'M A LITTLE BIT MAD BECAUSE
I HAVE TO RESPECT THEIR
DECISION, SO IT CONFRONTS ME AND
MY VALUES, BUT I THINK THEY
DIDN'T DO THEIR JOB.
>> Reporter: THE DOCTOR IS NOW A
FREE MAN WITH NO CRIMINAL
RECORD, AND HE SAYS HE'S NOT
TAKING ANY MEDICATION FOR MENTAL
ILLNESS.
THE ONLY CONDITIONS OF HIS
RELEASE ARE THAT HE CONTINUE
WITH THERAPY AND STAY AWAY FROM
HIS EX-WIFE AND HER FAMILY.
HE MUST ALSO GO BEFORE THE
REVIEW PANEL THAT RELEASED HIM
IN A YEAR.
THE MEDICAL PROFESSIONALS
CURRENTLY TREATING THE DOCTOR
AND THE PSYCHIATRIC EXPERTS WHO
GAVE TESTIMONY AT HIS TRIAL HAVE
TOLD CNN THEY DO NOT WISH TO
COMMENT ON THE CASE.
DR. GASTON SAYS SHE FEARS FOR
HER LIFE NOW, AND BELIEVES THE
PSYCHIATRISTS THAT TESTIFIED ON
HIS BEHALF DID NOT EVALUATE HIM
LONG ENOUGH.
SHE IS CALLING FOR STRICTER
GUIDELINES WHEN PSYCHIATRIC
TESTIMONY IS PRESENTED IN COURT.
SHE SAYS SHE HAS NEVER BELIEVED
HER EX-HUSBAND WAS MENTALLY ILL,
AND EVEN IF HE WAS, HE COULD NOT
NOW BE CURED IN LITTLE MORE THAN
THREE YEARS.
>> WHAT I'M SAYING, I HAVE
QUESTION.
I'M A MOTHER BUT I'M ALSO A
DOCTOR.
>> YOU HOPE IT WILL HELP OTHER
VICTIMS IN THE FUTURE?
>> YES, I HOPE.
AND YOU KNOW WHAT, I'M VERY
CONVINCED.
I'M WILLING TO LOSE MY HEALTH,
I'M WILLING TO LOSE MY ECONOMY
STATUS, I'M WILLING TO LOSE MY
PROFESSIONAL STATUS, I'M WILLING
TO LOSE MY LIFE.
I'M WILLING TO GO VERY FAR IN
THIS BATTLE.
AND I'M REALLY, REALLY CONVINCED
THAT IT HAS TO CHANGE.
>> DID YOU EVER ASK HIM WHY HE
DID IT?
>> I WANTED TO ASK HIM, BUT, YOU
KNOW, THE RESPONSE THAT HE'S
GOING TO GIVE ME, IF HE DOESN'T
TELL ME THE TRUTH, THAT IS MY
TRUTH THAT I KNOW IS FOR
VENGEANCE, YOU KNOW.
HE WILL INVENT EVERYTHING, AND
THAT'S WHAT HE DID IN COURT, YOU
KNOW.
>> AND DR. GASTON SAYS SHE
BELIEVES IT WILL BE AN IMPORTANT
TEST CASE TO POSSIBLY LIMIT
CLAIMS OF MENTAL INSANITY AND
BETTER SCRUTINIZE THE MEDICAL
EVIDENCE NEEDED TO PROVE IT.
>> THAT IS SUCH A HORRIFIC
CRIME.
PAULA NEWTON JOINS ME NOW.
PAULA, WHAT'S BEEN THE REACTION
TO THIS RELEASE?
>> Reporter: OUTRAGE REALLY
THROUGHOUT THE COUNTRY, FELT
MOST ACUTELY HERE IN MONTREAL
HERE TODAY, ANDERSON.
EVERYONE WAS TALKING ABOUT IT.
THE OUTRAGE STEMS FROM TWO
THING.
ONE OF THE THINGS IN THE
HEADLINES, LOOK, ANDERSON, THIS
GUY STABBED HIS CHILDREN 46
TIMES, HE CONFESSED TO IT.
HE SERVED 46 MONTHS, NOT ALL OF
IT IN PRISON.
HE IS A FREE MAN RIGHT NOW.
ADD TO THAT THAT THE MENTAL
FACILITY ACTUALLY SAID, LOOK,
THIS GUY DOES PRESENT A RISK TO
SOCIETY.
WE DON'T KNOW HOW HE'LL BEHAVE
IN THE FUTURE, BUT HE NEEDS TO
BE FREE AND WE CAN MANAGE THAT
RISK.
ANDERSON, I'LL REMIND YOU, THERE
WILL BE NO POLICE OFFICER
FOLLOWING HIM AROUND.
NOT ANYTHING LIKE THAT.
AND THE PUBLIC WANTS TO KNOW
WHY.
>> I MEAN THAT'S JUST
INCREDIBLE.
FOR SUCH A SHORT AMOUNT OF TIME
THAT HE ACTUALLY WAS IN THIS
MENTAL HEALTH FACILITY.
WHAT IS NEXT FOR HIM?
>> Reporter: WELL, THIS IS THE
OTHER OUTRAGEOUS THING PEOPLE
ARE TELLING ME.
IN HIS TESTIMONY AS TO WHY HE
WANTED TO BE RELEASED, HE SAID
HE WANTED TO LEAD A NORMAL LIFE.
HE'S GOING TO APPLY AGAIN TO
PRACTICE MEDICINE.
HE IS A CARDIOLOGIST, HE DOESN'T
HAVE ANY COMPLAINTS AGAINST HIM
IN TERMS OF THE KIND OF CARE HE
HAD FOR HIS PATIENTS.
HE IS FREE TO BE A DOCTOR AGAIN
IF HE GETS LICENSED ONCE MORE.
AND AGAIN, THE ONLY THING THAT
THE MOTHER, ISABELLE GASTON
KEEPS RELYING UPON IS AN APPEAL
IN THE NEW YEAR.
>> THAT'S JUST EXTRAORDINARY.
WE'LL CONTINUE TO FOLLOW IT.
THANK YOU.
>>> STILL AHEAD, A MURDER
MYSTERY WITH A TWIST.
DOLPHINS ARE TURNING UP DEAD
ALONG THE GULF COAST BUT WHO OR
WHAT IS KILLING THEM?
ED LAVANDERA HAS A SPECIAL
REPORT AHEAD.
THERE'S THE SIGN TO THE BULLPEN.
HERE HE COMES.
YOU WOULDN'T WANT YOUR
DOCTOR DOING YOUR JOB,
THE PITCH!
WHOA!
SO WHY ARE YOU DOING HIS?
ONLY YOUR DOCTOR CAN DETERMINE
IF YOUR PERSISTENT HEARTBURN
IS ACTUALLY SOMETHING
MORE SERIOUS
LIKE ACID REFLUX DISEASE.
OVER TIME, STOMACH
ACID CAN DAMAGE
THE LINING OF YOUR ESOPHAGUS.
FOR MANY, PRESCRIPTION NEXIUM
NOT ONLY PROVIDES
24-HOUR HEARTBURN RELIEF,
BUT CAN ALSO HELP HEAL
ACID-RELATED EROSIONS IN
THE LINING OF YOUR ESOPHAGUS.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT THE
RISK FOR OSTEOPOROSIS-RELATED
BONE FRACTURES AND
LOW MAGNESIUM LEVELS
WITH LONG-TERM USE OF NEXIUM.
POSSIBLE SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE
HEADACHE, DIARRHEA,
AND ABDOMINAL PAIN.
OTHER SERIOUS STOMACH
CONDITIONS MAY STILL EXIST.
LET YOUR DOCTOR DO HIS JOB.
AND YOU DO YOURS.
ASK IF NEXIUM IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
IF YOU CAN'T AFFORD
YOUR MEDICATION,
ASTRAZENECA MAY BE ABLE TO HELP.
>>> MURDER MYSTERY ALONG THE
GULF COAST IS DEEPENING TONIGHT.
MUTILATED BODIES OF DOLPHINS
HAVE BEEN WASHING ASHORE ALL
YEAR.
IN RECENT WEEKS THE PACE HAS
PICKED UP DRAMATICALLY.
AS MANY AS TEN DEAD DOLPHINS
HAVE BEEN FOUND.
THE DISCOVERY IS GRUESOME,
DISTURBING AND FRANKLY BAFFLING.
COULD IT BE THE WORK OF SOME
KIND OF A SERIAL KILLER?
IF SO, WHY WOULD ANYONE WANT TO
HARM DOLPHINS.
THAT'S WHAT A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE
WONDERING TONIGHT.
THE RACE TO SOLVE THE MYSTERY
HAS BEEN INTENSIFYING.
ED LAVANDERA REPORTS.
>> Reporter: THE HUNT IS ON.
>> WE'RE GOING TO DO A ROUTINE
SAFETY CHECK.
>> Reporter: FOR A DOLPHIN
KILLER.
>> THE DOLPHIN CASE IS IN THE
BACK OF YOUR MIND?
>> RIGHT.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO COME OUT AND
ASK HIM ARE YOU SHOOTING
DOLPHINS.
>> PERMISSION TO COME ON BOARD?
>> WE'RE GOING TO LOOK AND SEE
IF THERE'S ANY EVIDENCE AS FAR
AS FIREARMS AND SUCH LIKE THAT.
>> FIREARMS?
GUNS.
>> Reporter: OFFICER LEO
DEGEORGE AND A MISSISSIPPI
MARINE PATROL UNIT ARE SEARCHING
ANY BOAT THEY CAN FIND, TRYING
TO UNRAVEL THE MYSTERIOUS AND
DISTURBING CASE OF MURDERED
DOLPHINS WASHING UP ALONG THE
GULF COAST.
>> I'M GOING TO GO DOWN BELOW
AND TAKE A LOOK, SEE WHAT I CAN
FIND OUT.
>> Reporter: THERE'S A GROWING
SENSE OF URGENCY.
BETWEEN JANUARY AND NOVEMBER OF
THIS YEAR, SEVEN SLAIN DOLPHINS
HAVE BEEN FOUND.
BUT IN THE LAST TWO WEEKS, TWO
MORE DOLPHINS AND A PART OF A
THIRD WASHED ASHORE.
SOME HAVE BEEN SHOT, SOME
MUTILATED WITH TAILS AND A JAW
CUT OFF.
ONLY THE HEAD OF ONE DOLPHIN WAS
RECENTLY FOUND ON A BEACH.
MANY PICTURES TOO GRUESOME TO
SHOW.
>> SO THE ONE THING IT ALL HAS
IN COMMON IS ALL THESE DOLPHINS
HAVE TURNED UP ALONG THESE
LITTLE BARRIER ISLANDS ALONG THE
GULF COAST?
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
>> Reporter: MOBY IS THE LEAD
BIOLOGIST AT THE INSTITUTE FOR
MARINE MAMMAL STUDIES IN
GULFPORT, MISSISSIPPI.
HE'S ANALYZED THE CORPSES OF ALL
THE DOLPHINS FOR FEDERAL
INVESTIGATORS AT NOAA, THE
NATIONAL OCEANIC AND ATMOSPHERIC
ADMINISTRATION.
THERE NOW COULD BE AS MANY AS
TEN MURDERED DOLPHINS, THE
MAJORITY DISCOVERED IN THE LAST
TWO MONTHS.
>> WHAT DO YOU TAKE AWAY FROM
ALL THAT?
>> WELL, IT LOOKS LIKE SOMEBODY
IS DERANGED.
IT'S REALLY SENSELESS.
IT'S REPUGNANT, IT'S ILLEGAL.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND WHAT TYPE OF
PERSON WOULD DO SUCH A CRUEL
ACT.
>> Reporter: WHEN WE FIRST
STARTED ASKING QUESTIONS ABOUT
THE DEAD DOLPHINS A FEW WEEKS
AGO, WE ASKED FEDERAL
INVESTIGATORS IF THEY THOUGHT
THIS COULD BE THE WORK OF A
DOLPHIN SERIAL KILLER OR
KILLERS.
THEY TOLD US THEN THAT THAT WAS
NOT ONE OF THEIR THEORIES, BUT
SINCE THEN, THREE MORE DOLPHINS
HAVE WASHED ASHORE, AND THOSE
FEDERAL INVESTIGATORS NOW SAY
THEY CAN'T COMMENT ON AN ACTIVE
CRIMINAL INVESTIGATION.
>> YOU'VE SEEN THESE ANIMALS UP
CLOSE.
WERE YOU ABLE TO SEE ANYTHING
THAT KIND OF LEADS YOU TO
BELIEVE THAT IT MIGHT HAVE BEEN
THE WORK OF ONE PERSON?
>> WELL, IT'S REALLY HARD FOR US
TO DO, BECAUSE ALL WE CAN DO AS
SCIENTISTS IS REPORT THE FACT,
THE INVESTIGATIVE AGENCIES AND
PEOPLE WHO ARE TRAINED TO
DETERMINE WHAT KIND OF
CONNECTIONS AND WHAT TYPE OF
PROFILE A PERSON HAS.
>> Reporter: FEDERAL
INVESTIGATORS TOLD US A FEW
WEEKS AGO THEY THINK THE MURDERS
ARE NOT CONNECTED.
BUT ALONG THIS COASTLINE TODAY,
MANY PEOPLE ARE WONDERING IF
THERE'S A DERANGED DOLPHIN
SERIAL KILLER OR KILLERS HUNTING
THESE BELOVED CREATURES.
ON PATROL, WILD DOLPHINS BOB UP
AND DOWN ALL AROUND US.
THE MYSTERIOUS STRING OF DOLPHIN
KILLINGS IS SOMETHING THESE
OFFICERS HAVE NEVER SEEN.
>> WHAT'S YOUR BIGGEST FEAR
ABOUT THE WAY ALL OF THIS IS
PLAYING OUT?
>> THE BIGGEST FEAR?
MORE OF THEM.
AND WHY WOULD SOMEBODY DO THIS?
I DON'T KNOW HOW THEY'RE GETTING
A THRILL OUT OF THIS.
>> Reporter: AND THE SEARCH
INTENSIFIES FOR A PREDATOR
LURKING AROUND THESE WATERS.
ED LAVANDERA, CNN, ON THE
MISSISSIPPI SOUND.
>> WELL, NOW ISHA JOINS WITH US
A 360 NEWS AND BUSINESS
BULLETIN.
>> ANDERSON, BRITISH POLICE SAY
THE WOMAN WHO WHO TOOK A CALL
REGARDING THE DUCHESS OF YORK
COMMITTED SUICIDE.
SHE LEFT THREE SUICIDE NOTES.
>>> FISCAL CLIFF FEARS ON WALL
STREET, DOW DROPPING 74 POINTS.
DESPITE THE RELEASE OF UPBEAT
ECONOMIC DATA.
NOW MANY MERCHANTS ARE SWEATING
IT OUT.
IN WASHINGTON SOME COMMUNITY
LEADERS ARE POINTING TO A LOCAL
INITIATIVE TO PROVE THAT EVEN
TOUGH ECONOMIES CAN BE BEATEN.
TOM HAS TONIGHT'S AMERICAN
JOURNEY.
>> YOU EVER TRAVEL AROUND THE
WHOLE WORLD, WHAT YOU WILL
NOTICE IS THIS IS THE NORMAL WAY
TO DO BUSINESS.
>> FAR FROM THE MALLS IN THE
MIDDLE OF DOWNTOWN D.C., THE
HOLIDAY MARKET IS ONCE AGAIN
SWINGING TO LIFE WITH OLD WORLD
CHARM.
FOR EIGHT YEARS NOW, EVEN
THROUGH THE DARKEST DAYS OF
RECESSION IT HAS BEEN A STEADILY
GROWING STORY OF SUCCESS FOR
HUNDREDS OF ARTISANS AND DRAFT
DEALERS SELLING PRODUCT FROM
AROUND THE GLOBE.
MICHAEL HELPS RUN THE MARKET
WHICH WAS STARTED IN PART IT
DRAW MORE SHOPPERS TO THE AREA.
HOW MANY PEOPLE COME THROUGH
HERE?
WE'RE GETTING ABOUT 10,000
PEOPLE A DAY.
IT WAS SO CROWDED, I THINK THE
NUMBER MIGHT HAVE DOUBLED.
>> ASHLEY ROBINSON IS A SOAP
MAKER FROM VIRGINIA WHOSE
INVENTORY HAS ALREADY ALMOST
SOLD OUT.
>> OH, MY GOSH, WE BROUGHT A BUS
AND WE ALMOST EMPTIED IT.
A BUS FULL OF STOCK, YEAH.
>> RON CAME ALL THE WAY FROM
TEXAS TO OFFER BUFFALO HATS AND
YOU'VE SOLD HOW MANY?
>> ABOUT 200.
>> IN WHAT PERIOD OF TIME?
>> A WEEK.
>> YEAH.
IF YOU WALK UP AND DOWN THE
STREET HERE, YOU WILL SEE A
BUNCH OF THEM HERE IN THE NEXT
COUPLE OF HOURS.
>> THE MARKET HAS PROVEN A GREAT
PLACE FOR VENDORS TO TEST
PRODUCTS BEFORE OPENING
TRADITIONAL BRICK AND MORTAR
STORES.
>> WITHOUT THE BURDEN, OF
JUMPING INTO THE DEEP END OF THE
POOL WITH RENT AND INSURANCE AND
ALL OF THE HEAVY DUTY INVESTMENT
THAT YOU HAVE TO DO.
BUT ONCE YOU KNOW YOU'RE GOING
TO BE SUCCESSFUL, NOW CAN YOU GO
FORWARD.
>> AND YOU'VE HAD THAT HAPPEN
HERE A LOT.
>> WE HAVE.
>> STALLS ARE SO PRIZED AND
SPACE LIMITED, THERE IS NOT
ENOUGH ROOM FOR ALL OF THE
VENDORS THAT WANT TO BE HERE.
BUT FOR THOSE CHOSEN EACH YEAR
FOR A FEW LUCKY WEEKS --
>> LET ME JUST PUT IT ON THERE.
>> THE HOLIDAYS ARE TRULY CAUSE
FOR CELEBRATION.
>> OH GREAT.
THANK YOU.
>> CNN, WASHINGTON.
>> AND IT IS GOOD TO SEE.
ANDERSON WILL BE RIGHT BACK WITH
THE RIDICULIST.
TRY RUNNING FOUR.NING
A RESTAURANT IS HARD,
FORTUNATELY WE'VE GOT INK.
IT GIVES US 5X THE REWARDS
ON OUR INTERNET, PHONE
CHARGES AND CABLE,
PLUS AT OFFICE SUPPLY STORES.
REWARDS WE PUT RIGHT
BACK INTO OUR BUSINESS.
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
WE'VE EVER WANTED TO DO
AND INK HELPS US DO IT.
MAKE YOUR MARK
WITH INK FROM CHASE.
AT THE CHEVY YEAR-END EVENT
BECAUSE CHEVY'S GIVING MORE.
MORE EFFICIENCY
WITH SONIC AND CRUZE...
MORE FUNCTION
IN EQUINOX AND TRAVERSE...
MORE DEPENDABILITY
WITH THE LEGENDARY SILVERADO...
AND MORE STYLE
IN THE ALL-NEW MALIBU.
CHEVY'S GIVING MORE
AT THE YEAR-END EVENT
BECAUSE 'TIS THE SEASON.
CHEVY'S GIVING MORE.
THIS HOLIDAY SEASON,
GET A 2013 CRUZE LS
FOR AROUND $149 PER MONTH
OR GET $500 HOLIDAY BONUS CASH.
Capella University understands
back from rough economic times.
Employees are being forced to do
more with less.
And the need for capable leaders
is greater than ever.
When you see these problems do
you take a step back,
or do you want to dive right in?
With a degree in business from
Capella University, you'll have
the knowledge to go further in
your career than you ever
thought possible.
Let's get started at CAPELLA.EDU
TO TAKE A CENTRUM SILVER
MULTIVITAMIN EVERY DAY.
I TOLD HIM, SURE.
CAN'T HURT, RIGHT?
THEN I HEARD THIS NEWS
ABOUT A MULTIVITAMIN STUDY
LOOKING AT LONG-TERM
HEALTH BENEFITS FOR MEN OVER 50.
THE ONE THEY USED
IN THAT STUDY...
CENTRUM SILVER.
THAT'S WHAT I TAKE.
MY DOCTOR!
HE KNOWS HIS STUFF.
[ Male Announcer ] CENTRUM.
THE MOST RECOMMENDED.
MOST PREFERRED.
MOST STUDIED.
CENTRUM,
ALWAYS YOUR MOST COMPLETE.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
Schwab Bank was built with all
the value and convenience
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
investors want.
Like no ATM fees, worldwide.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
And no nuisance fees.
Plus deposit checks with
Mobile Deposit.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
And manage your cash
and investments
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
with Schwab's mobile app.
No wonder Schwab Bank has grown
to over 70 billion in assets.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
So if you're looking for a bank
that's in your corner,
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
not just on the corner...
Call, click or visit to start
banking with Schwab Bank today.
TDD#: 1-800-345-2550
>>> TIME FOR THE RIDICULIST.
TONIGHT WE'RE ADDING SOMETHING
I'M CALLING THE CNBC DANGER
ZONE.
NO, THAT'S NOT THE NAME OF A NEW
SHOW WHERE MARIA BARTIROMO AND
WARREN BUFFETT GO ROCK CLIMBING.
THOUGH FRANKLY I THINK IT SHOULD
BE.
THE CNBC DANGER ZONE IS WHAT
HAPPENED WHEN GLENN HUBBARD SAT
DOWN FOR AN INTERVIEW WITH
MELISSA LEE.
EVERYTHING WAS GOING FINE UNTIL
I CAN ONLY ASSUME THE NBC
PEACOCK GOT A LITTLE FIESTY OFF
CAMERA.
>> THEY EITHER HAVE TO RAISE
TAXES OR CUT SOME OTHER
SPENDING.
THAT FORCES THE CONGRESS TO
THINK ABOUT THE MIX BETWEEN
TAXES, SPENDING OUTSIDE OF THE
ENTITLEMENTS AND SPENDING ON THE
ENTITLEMENTS.
THAT'S JUST NOT SOMETHING THAT
OUR FRAMERS THOUGHT ABOUT
BECAUSE WE DIDN'T HAVE A WELFARE
STATE IN THOSE DAYS.
>> FIRST OF ALL, I LOVE HOW HE
CONTINUED ON, MAKING HIS POINTS.
THAT IS WHAT YOU CALL A PRO.
SECOND OF ALL, YOU WILL NOT SEE
CNN GUESTS RUNNING INTO THAT
PROBLEM.
WE DO NOT WASTE OUR MONEY ON
FANCY, DANGEROUS SIGNS FOR OUR
REMOTE LOCATIONS.
ALL DAVID GERGEN NEEDS IS SOME
LIP GLOSS AND A LAVA LAMP AND
HE'S GOOD TO GO.
CNN ANCHORS HAVE ENCOUNTERED
SOME ON-SET MISHAPS AND IT TURNS
OUT IT IS A GLOBAL PROBLEM.
[ SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE ]
>> LOOSELY TRANSLATED, THAT WAS
DAMN YOU, WOLF BLITZER.
OF COURSE THERE ARE A LOT OF
POTENTIAL HAZARDS FOR FOLKS ON
TV.
SOMETIMES A SIGN FALLS,
SOMETIMES THE LIGHTS FALL AND
SOMETIMES AS OUR FRIEND FROM
WSMV REMINDS US, EVEN THE
REPORTER FALLS.
>> AND LOOK, THEY'RE BIG.
THIS ONE IS ABOUT 12 POUNDS, BUT
THEY CAN GROW TO --
[ LAUGHING ]