THAT KNOCK DOWN DRAGOUT FIGHT
STARTED AS COMEDY BUT QUICKLY IT
TURNED VERY VERY REAL.
MASCOTS GETTING VIOLENT.
THE RAM AND THE PANTHER PULLING
EACH OTHER TO THE GROUND AND
THROWING PUNCHES.
THE HALFTIME BRAWL DIDN'T END
UNTIL OTHERS STEPPED IN TO PULL
THE MASCOTS APART, BUT DON'T
WORRY.
THE RAM AND THE PANTHER WERE NOT
HURT.
THAT'S THE LAST CALL.
THANKS FOR BEING WITH US
TONIGHT.
SEE YOU TOMORROW NIGHT.
GO TO GRETAWIRE.COM.
THERE'S AN OPEN THREAD.
TELL US WHAT YOU THOUGHT ABOUT
TONIGHT'S SHOW.
GRETAWEAR.COM.
GOODNIGHT FROM WASHINGTON.
>> Bill: THE O'REILLY FACTOR IS
ON.
TONIGHT ...
>> THE ONLY THING LEFT FOR
BARACK OBAMA TO DO IS TO WORRY
ABOUT THE THIRD WORLD
DICTATORSES AND PUT ALL THESE
GUYS IN JAIL.
>> HE'S TALKING ABOUT ME, YOUR
HUMBLE CORRESPONDENT.
THIS EVENING, WE WILL CONTINUE
OUR REPORTING.
THE FAR LEFT ON THE MARCH.
[ MUSIC ]
>> Bill: YOUNG SINGERS TAYLOR
SWIFT AND KAT KATY PERRY UNDER E
BY A RADICAL FEMINIST WHO SAID
THEY ARE INSIPID.
>>> DEFINEF THE FISCAL CLIFF FOR
ME.
SOME IMAGINARY CLIFF IN MY MIND
THAT WE'RE GOING TO JUMP OFF OF.
>> Bill: JESSE WATT IERS QUIZES
FOLKS ABOUT THE FISCAL CLIFF.
CAUTION.
YOU ARE ABOUT TO ENTER THE NO
SPIN ZONE.
THE FACTOR BEGINS RIGHT NOW.
>>> HI.
I'M BILL O'REILLY.
THANKS FOR WATCHING US TONIGHT.
SECULAR FORCES ON THE MARCH.
THAT IS THE SUBJECT OF THIS
EVENING'S TALKING POINTS MEMO.
AS WE HAVE BEEN REPORTING.
SOME COMMITTED LEFT WING
AMERICANS HAVE BEEN EMBOLDENED
BY THE REELECTION OF PRESIDENT
OBAMA.
YOU'RE SEEING THAT NOW IN THE
BUDGET NEGOTIATIONS AS THE
PRESIDENT AND HIS SIDE ARE NOT
IN ANY COMPROMISING MOOD.
I SAW IT FIRSTHAND THIS WEEK
WHEN I WAS DOWN IN WASHINGTON.
THERE IS ARROGANCE AND CON DESEN
SHUN IN MANY LEFT WING PRECINCTS
DESPIEGHT THDESPITE THE FACT THN
AMBASSADOR TODAY SUSAN RICE IS
OUT IN CONSIDERATION FOR
SECRETARY OF STATE.
WE'LL HAVE MORE ON THAT COMING
UP.
THE MORE INTELLIGENT SECULAR
PROGRESSIVES UNDERSTAND THAT NOW
IS THEIRSI TIME IN HISTORY.
THE AGENDA IS CLEAR.
ABOVE ALL, THE SECULAR FORCES
WANT TO CHANGE THE ECONOMY.
THEY WANT THE GOVERNOR TO RUN IT
AND PROVIDE CRADLE TO GRAVE
ENTITLEMENTS FOR THOSE WHO
CANNOT AND WILL NOT PROVIDE FOR
THEMSELF.
THEY WANT TO S CONTROL PROFITS,
TAKING AS MUCH MONEY AS POSSIBLE
AWAY FROM THE ACHIEVERS AND THE
CORPORATIONS WITH THEHE INTENT O
REDISTRIBUTE THE CASH.
THAT'S AGENDA NUMBER ONE.
NUMBER TWO IS TO OBLITERATE SOME
AMERICAN TRADITIONS.
GAY MARRIAGE, NOT ABOUT MATRY MW
KNEE ANY MORE.
IF YOU OPPOSE GAY MARRIAGE,
YOU'RE A HEIGHTR OR A RIGHTS
DENYR.
LEGALIZE NARCOTICS.
THE LEFT SEES DRUG USERS AS
VICTIMS AND BELIEVES NO ONE HAS
A RIGHT TO STAND BETWEEN AN
AMERICAN AND INTOXICATION.
ON THAT NOT, THERE WAS AN
ARTICLE YESTERDAY IN THE "NEW
YORK TIMES" LANG MEANTING TOUGH
PRISON SENTENCES FOR DRUG
OFFENDERS.
THE LEFT BELIEVES THEY'RE NOT
VIOLENT.
IF YOU'RE SELLING METH, HEROIN,
COCAINE, THAT'S NOT AN ACTED
THAT CAUSES HARM OR PAIN TO
ANOTHER PERSON, OH, NO.
ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
THOSE OF YOU WHO KNOW FIRSTHAND
ABOUT ADDICTION KNOW HOW CRAZY
THAT POINT OF VIEW IS.
HO SELL DRUGS ARE THE
LOWEST RUNNING.
THEY ARE COMMITTING VIOLENCE
AGAINST OTHER HUMAN BEINGS,
PERIOD.
THE TIMES ARTICLE SAYS HALF A
MILLION PEOPLE ARE IN PRISON FOR
DRUG OFFENSES IN THE USA, TEN
TIMES THE NUMBER THAN IN 1980.
THAT SOUNDS BAD, DOESN'T IT?
WHAT THE PAPER DOES NOT, DOES
NOT TELL YOU IS THAT VIOLENT
CRIME IN AMERICA HAS BEEN CUT IN
HALF SINCE THE TOUGH MANDATORY
PRISON SENTENCES WERE
INSTITUTED.
COUNTRIES MUCH SAFER BECAUSE
HARD CORE CRIMINALS ARE DOING
HARD TIME. THAT'S A FACT.
NO ONE SHOULD FEEL SORRY FOR
KILLERS, F RAPISTS, AND DRUG
PUSHERS.
NOW, BECAUSE I DO COMMENTARY
LIKE THIS, LAYING OUT THE
PROGRESSIVE AGENDA, I'M A BIG
THREAT TO THEM.
LISTEN TO THIS INCREDIBLE SOUND
BITE FROM COMMITTED LEFT WING
GUYNG HARRY BELAFONTE.
HE SAID PEOPLE LIKE ME WHO
OPPOSE PRESIDENT OBAMA AND THE
LIB RA AGENDA ON SOME THINGS
SHOULD BE DEALT WITH.
>> WHAT FASCINATES ME IS THAT IN
THE FACE OF MILLIONS OF
AMERICANS EXPRESSING THEIR
DESIRE, THE WHOLE POLITICAL
ESTABLISHMENT DEFINING ITS GAME
THAT THERE SHOULD BE THIS
LINGERING INFESTATION OF REALLY
CORRUPT PEOPLE WHO ARE STILL
TRYING TO DISMANTLE THE WISHES
OF THEOF PEOPLE, THE MANDATE THT
HAS BEENTH GIVEN TO BARACK OBAM,
AND I DON'T KNOW WHAT MORE THEY
WANT.
THE ONLY THING LEFT FOR BARACK
OBAMA TO DO IS TO ORGANIZE THE
THIRD WORLD DICTATORS AND THROW
THESE GUYS IN JAIL FOR VIOLATING
THE AMERICAN DESIRE.
>> I GUESS VIOLATING THE
AMERICAN DESIRE IS A FELONY NOW,
RIGHT, HARRY?
MAYBE THE GUY WAS JUST KIDDING.
MAYBE.
BUT BELIEVE ME.
ANYONE IN THIS COUNTRY WHO
CHALLENGES THE SECULAR
PROGRESSIVE AGENDA IS GOING TO
GET HAMMERED.
THEY WANT A COUNTRY THAT
EMABRASIONS SOCIAEMBRACES SOCIA.
THAT BRINGS US TO THE CHRISTMAS
CONTROVERSY WHICH IS SYMBOLIC,
SYMBOLIC OF THE CUL CULTURE WAR.
A COUPLE OF WEEKS AGO A MAGAZINE
CITED RETAIL STORES ALLOWING
EMPLOYEES TO NOW SAY MERRY
CHRISTMAS TO THE SHOPPERS.
YEARS AGO CORPORATIONS WERE
FORBIDDEN.
THEY WERE TELLING EMPLOYEES THEY
COULDN'T DO THAT.
WHILE
THE WAR ON CHRISTMAS HAS
LARGELY GONE OUR WAY, DON'T
THINK IT'S OVER.
IT'S NOT.
LISTEN TO THIS EXCHANGE ABOUT
THE CHRISTMAS HOLIDAY ON THE
"TODAY" SHOW EARLIER THIS WEEK.
>> I FOCUS ON HONESTLY THE
RELIGION PART OF IT.
I REALLY AND TRULY DO, SO I
CAN'T OUTSOURCE THAT PART OF IT.
I CAN SEND YOU TO GET MY TREE,
BUT YOU CAN'T HELP ME.
>> I DON'T LIKE THE RELIGION
PART.
I THINK RELIGION IS WHAT MUCKS
THE WHOLE THING UP.
>> Bill: SOME AMERICANS AGREE
WITH DR. SNYDERMAN THERE, THAT
BECAUSE CHRISTMAS
HONORS JESUS
WHO SOME PEOPLE BELIEVE IS GOD,
THAT IT'S MUCKED UP.
MUCKED UP, SO TO SPEAK.
TV WRITER FRAZIER MOORE WRITES,
QUOTE, TURNING THE NO SPIN ZONE
INTO A HOLIDAY WAR ZONE.
O'REILLY IS ALL FOR KEEPING
CHRIST IN CHRISTMAS.
AT THE SAME TIME HECH PROCLAIMS
THAT EVERYONE, NO MATTER THEIR
FAITH, SHOULD CALL A CHRISTMAS
TREE A CHRISTMAS TREE AND KNOCK
OFF THEIR WHINING.
NO INTELLIGENT PERSON COULD
POSSIBLY SEE AS A SECULAR
DISPLAY OF CHRISTMAS AS AN
IMPOSITION OF RELIGION.
HE DECLARED.
IT'S A PHILOSOPHY.
HE TOLD HIS AUDIENCE.
NEVER MIND THAT WEBSTER'S NEW
WORLDAS COLLEGE DICTIONARY DEFIS
CHRISTIANITY A AS THE CHRISTIANS
COLLECTIVELY.
MOOR IS ONE OF THE LEGIONS OF
MEDIA WHO HAVE FORMED A SECULAR
CLOWN TOE TOES SEE, POSSE.
SO I'MSO GOING TO SPEAK VERY
SLOWLY TO YOU, FRAZIER.
PLEASE TAKE SOME NOTES.
HAVE THAT DICTIONARY HANDY.
CHRISTIANITY IS A RELIGION FOR
THOSE WHO BELIEVE JESUS IS GOD,
AND FOR THOSE WHO JOIN A
TO CELEBRATECH
THAT BELIEF, BUT CHRISTIANITY IS
A PHILOSOPHY TO PEOPLE LIKE
THOMAS JEFFERSON WHO DID NOT
BELIEVE THAT JESUS WAS THE
DEITY, AND MR. JEFFERSON AS WELL
AS MANY OF THE FOUNDING FACTS
INCORPORATED THE JUDEO-CHRISTIAN
PHILOSOPHY INTO THE
CONSTITUTION.
THAT'S WHY THE TEN COMMANDMENTS
HANG IN THE SUPREME COURT
BUILDING.
ARE YOU WITH ME SO FAR, FRAZIER?
IMAGES OF THE MANGERR SCENE IN
THE PUBLIC SQUARE SIMPLY HONOR
THE BABY JESUS, THE HUMAN BEING.
THE BABY IS NOT SITTING AT THE
RIGHT HAND OF GOD.
HE IS LAYING THERE FLANKED BY
HIS PARENTS.
IT'S LIKE THE MARTIN LUTHER
KING, JR. HOLIDAY, FRAZIER.
DR. KING HONORED AS A MAN WHO
HELPED ME HUMANITY.
AT CHRISTMAS, JESUS IS HONORED
AS A MAN WHO HELPED HUMANITY.
IF YOU WANT TO BELIEVE JESUS IS
GOD, THEN YOU CAN TAKE THAT
FURTHER AS IS YOUR
CONSTITUTIONAL RIGHT.
IF YOU DON'T BUY THE RELIGIOUS
ASPECT, YOU CAN JUST CELEBRATE
THE FEDERAL HOLIDAY THAT WAS
SIGNED INTO LAW BY PRESIDENT
GRANT WITH NO PROVISION,
FRAZIER, THAT EVERYONE WORSHIP
JESUS.
NOT PART OF THE DEAL.
ARE YOU STILL WITH ME?
OR IS THIS TOO COMPLICATED FOR
YOU?
HERE'S THE BIG PICTURE.
THE SECULAR PROGRESSIVE AGENDA
IS OPPOSED BY MANY PEOPLE OF
FAITH.F
ABORTION, GAY MARRIAGE,
LEGALIZED DRUGS, ALL OF THOSE
THINGS ARE OPPOSED BY MANY
RELIGIOUS AMERICANS.
THAT IS WHY SOME FAR LEFT FOLKS
WANT TO DIMINISH JUDEO-CHRISTIAN
TRADITION AND RENAME THE
CHRISTMAS TREE THE HOLIDAY TREE.
THE LESS CHRISTMAS, THE BETTER.
THESE SECULAR PEOPLE ARE NOW
MORE POWERFUL THAN EVER.
THEIR GUY'S BEEN REELECTED AND
OPPOSING FORCES ARE SCATTERED,
AND THAT IS WHAT'S GOING ON IN
AMERICA ON DECEMBER 13th,
2012.
THAT'S IT.
NEXT ON THE RUNDOWN WE'LL HAVE
REACTION FROM BOB BECKEL AND LAW
RA INGRAHAM.
A MARINE INCARCERATED IN MEXICO
FOR NO REASON AT ALL.
THIS IS OUTRAGEOUS.
WE'RE TRYING TO GET HIM RELEASE.
WE'RE BACK IN A MOMENT.
AT THE T.
BUT LATER...
[ shirt ]
MERRY CHRISTMAS, EVERYBODY!
NOT SO MUCH.
HO HO HO!
THIS ISN'T
THAT KIND OF DEAL.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SAVE ON GROUND SHIPPING
AT FEDEX OFFICE.
You know how painful heartburn
can be.
For fast, long lasting relief,
use doctor recommended
Gaviscon®.
Only Gaviscon® forms a
protective barrier that helps
block stomach acid from
splashing up-
relieving the pain quickly.
Try fast, long lasting
Gaviscon®.
And also to build my career.
So I'm not about to always let
my frequent bladder urges,
or the worry my pipes
might leak get in the way
of my busy lifestyle.
That's why I take care,
with VESIcare.
Once-daily VESIcare can help
control your bladder muscle
and is proven to treat
overactive bladder
with sympts of
frequent urges and leaks
day and night.
If you have certain stomach or
glaucoma problems,
or trouble emptying
your bladder,
do not take VESIcare.
VESIcare may cause allergic
reactions that may be serious.
If you experience swelling of
the face, lips,
throat or tongue,
stop taking VESIcare
and get emergency help.
Tell your doctor right away if
you have severe abdominal pain,
or become constipated for three
or more days.
VESIcare may
cause blurred vision,
so use caution while driving
or doing unsafe tasks.
Common side effects
are dry mouth, constipation,
and indigestion.
I've worked hard
to get to where I am...
and I've got better
aces to go
than always
going to the bathroom.
So take charge of your symptoms
by talking to your doctor
and go to vesicare.com
for a free trial offer.
>> Bill: CONTINUING NOW WITH OUR
LEAD STORY, SECULAR FORCES ON
THEOW MARCH.
HERE NOW THE CO-HOST OF THE
FIVE, DEMOCRAT BOB BECKEL.
WHERE AM I GOING T WRONG?
>> EVERYWHERE.
>> Bill: I'M NOT WRITEIN RIGHT N
ANYTHING?
>> NONE OF THE THINGS YOU
LISTED.
>> Bill: NOT EVEN ON FRAZIER
MOORE.
>> I DON'T KNOW HIM, AND I DON'T
CARE, BUT HE JUST GOT HIS BUTT
SKINNED BY YOU.
HE SHOULDN'T BE SAYING THINGS
ABOUT YOU.
>> Bill: HE SHOULDN'T WRITE
THINGS THAT AREN'T TRUE.
HE DOESN'T KNOW THE DIFFERENT
BETWEEN CHRISTIAN PHILOSOPHY AND
CHRISTIANITY.
>> YOU FOUGHT THE WAR ON
CHRISTMAS AND YOU WON THE
BALLOT.
LET'S MOVE ON.
>> Bill: I'M NOT MOVING ON.
NUMBER ONE, IT'S SYMBOLIC OF THE
CULTURE WAR.
>> WHAT CULTURE WAR?
>> Bill: YOU DON'T BELIEVE
THERE'S ANY TENSION?
>>VE TRADITIONAL AMERICANS AND
SECULAR AMERICANS?
SO SECULAR AMERICANS ARE NOT
TRADITIONAL AMERICANS?
IS THAT WHAT YOU'RE SUGGESTING.
>> Bill: THAT'S TRUE.
THEY WANTWH CHANGE.
SECULAR PROGRESS AS I WAS WANT
TO CHANGE THE COUNTRY.
>>RY IT'S MIND BOG LING TO ME.
YOURil RADIO COMMENTARY, FOR
EXAMPLE, WAS BEYOND BELIEF.
GAY MARRIAGES.
YOU KNOW THE MAJORITY OF
AMERICANS FAVOR GAY MARRIAGE?
>> Bill: I DON'T OPPOSE GAY
MARRIAGE.
I DIDN'T SAYGE THAT.
IT'S AN ISSUE THAT'S DEFINED AS
A CIVIL RIGHTS ISSUE.
>> YOU SAID A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE
AGAINST GAY MARRIAGE.
>> Bill: THEY ARE.
>> NOT EVERYBODY.
PEOPLE WHO OPPOSE THEM ARE
MOSTLY AFRICAN-AMERICANS.
>> Bill: YOU'RE MEANDERING HERE.
>> I'M NOT MEANDERING ANYWHERE.
>> Bill: MY THES THESIS IS THERA
RAGING CULTURE WAR AN YOUR SIDE,
THE SECULAR PROGRESS AS I WAS,
ARPROGRESSIVES, AREEMBOLDENED B.
HARRY BELAFONTE IS CALL FOR THE
IMPRISONMENT OF ME.
>> HE WAS JOKING.
>> Bill: I DEBIT SE DIDN'T SEE M
SMILING THERE.
DID YOU?
HOW DO YOU KNOW HE WAS JOKING.
>> HE LAUGHED.
>> Bill: THE OTHER GUY LAUGHED
BECAUSE IT WAS SO INSANE.
HARRY WASN'T LAUGHING.
>> YOU THINK HARRY WANTS TO LOCK
YOU UP?
I THINK IT'S A WORTH WHILE
EXERCISE.
>> Bill: I THINK HARRY BE L
AFONTE WOULD PROBABLY EMBRACE
ANYTHING THAT WOULD GIVE HIM
WANTS POLITICALLY?
>> YOU KEEP SAYING THE SECULAR
LEFT AS IF THE SECULAR LEFT
REPRESENTS MAYBE 20% OF THE
DEMOGRAPHICS OF THIS COUNTRY.
VIRTUALLY EVERY ONE OF THESE
YOU'VE COME UP WITH C HERE, LIKE
FOR EXAMPLE, TAX INCREASES FOR
WEALTHY PEOPLE.E
THAT'S ACROSS THEHA BOARD.
REPUBLICANS WANT IT, TOO.
A LOT OF REPUBLICANS.
INDEPENDENTS BY BIG NUMBERS,
DEMOCRATS BY BIG NUMBERS.
>> Bill: LOOK.
IT'S NOT ABOUT A LITTLE TAX
HIKE.
IT'S ABOUT THE GOVERNMENT TAKING
OVER THE ECONOMY.
THAT'S WHAT SECULAR PROGRESSIVES
WANT.
THEY WANTTH TO DOLE OUT SOCIAL
JUSTICE, YOU KNOW THAT.
>> I DON'T KNOW THAT.
>> Bill: WHAT COUNTRY DO YOU
LIVE?
DO YOU JET OFF TO AL BAINIA?
>> YOU'RE THE ONE WHO JETS OFF,
I DON'T HAVE AE  JET OFF.
>> Bill: YOU DON'T ACKNOWLEDGE A
CULTURE WAR.
>> UNBELIEVABLE.
>> Bill: LET'S GO TO SUSAN RICE.
WERE YOU SURPRISED THAT THE UN
AMBASSADOR IS NOW NOT GOING TO
BE IN CONTENTION FOR SECRETARY
OF STATE.
>> NO.
>> Bill: WHY AREN'T YOU
SURPRISED?
>> THEY DIDN'T WANT TO PUT UP
WITH A BIG BATTLE IN THE SENATE
WHEN THEY'VE GOT A LOT OF OTHER
THINGS GOING ON.
JOHN KERRY IS A GOOD FALLBACK.
THAT WILL BE WHERE THEY'RE GOING
TO GO.
>> Bill: PRESIDENT OBAMA WAS
MAD.
HE WOULD HAVE LIKED TO HAVE HAD
SUSAN RICE IN THAT SPOT.
>> I THINK HE WOULD HAVE.
>> Bill: HE SAID HE'SNK ASHAMED
SHE WAS UNFAIRLY TREATED.
DO YOU BELIEVE SHE WAS UNFAIRLY
TREATED.
>> OH,IR YES.
SURE.
>> Bill: HOW WAS SHE UNFAIRLY
TREATED?
>> PEOPLE MADE ACCUSATIONS ABOUT
WHAT SHE SAID IN THE TALK SHOWS.
SHE WAS SPEAKING DIRECTLY FROM
THE INTELLIGENCE REPORTS SHE WAS
GIVEN.
>
>> Bill: WHY DIDN'T SHE CORRECT
THE RECORD LIKE A WEEK LATER.
>> SHE DID CORRECT THE RECORD.
>> Bill: WHEN?
WHERE?
>> FIRST OF ALL, SHE WAS -- I
THINK IT WAS IN THE UN.
>> Bill: THAT'SNOTTHE POINT.
I SAID THE>> YOU WANT TO FIGHT S
BENGHAZI THING ALL OVER AGAIN?
>> Bill: I DON'T WANT TO DO
ANYTHING.
I WANT TO KNOW T WHERE SHE
CORRECTED THE RECORD.
>> Bill: WAS IT AT A CLUB, A
DISCO IN NEW YORK.
>> I DON'T D CARE.
>> Bill: YOU DON'T CARE?
>> I DON'T CARE.
IT'S YOUR TYPICAL LET'S TRAP THE
GUY IN THE COMMENT.
>> Bill: YOU MADE A STATEMENT
THAT SHE CORRECTED THE RECORD
AND I SAID WHERE.
>> SHE WAS UNFAIRLY TREATED.
>
>> Bill: SHE DIDN'T CORRECT THE
RECORD.
IF SHE HAD, SHE WOULD BE OKAY.
SHE DIDN'T CORRECT IT.
>> DO YOU THINK SHE WOULD SAY
SHE WAS ACCURATE?
>> I DON'T KNOW WHAT SHE WOULD
SAY.
I HOPE SHE COMES ON HERE.
>> Bill: LET'S RECAP.
NO CUL CULTURE WAR IN YOUR OPINN
RIGHT.AC
>> Bill: DR. RICE CORRECTED THE
RECORD IN NEW YORK CITY, BUT YOU
DON'T KNOW WHERE, IT COULD HAVE
BEEN THE BRONX, STATEN ISLAND.
>> IT COULD HAVE BEEN IN
BROOKLYN.
>> Bill: BOB BECKEL,M  EVERYBOD.
WATCH A HIM ON THE FIVE.
LAURLAURA INGRAHAM WILL WEIGH IN
THE SECULAR PROGRESSIVES.
UDGET E
THIS FAMILY USED
Capital One Venture Miles
TO COME HOME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE...
SADLY, THEIR BROTHER'S
WHITE CHRISTMAS
JUST GOT "BLACKED OUT."
[ Brother ]
BUT IT'S THE FAMILY PARTY!
REALLY JINGLES YOUR BELLS,
DOESN'T IT?
MY GIFT TO YOU!
THE Capital One Venture Card!
FOR ANY FLIGHT, ANY TIME!
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE!
HOW ILLUMINATING.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
LET ME GUESS, AM
ON THE NAUGHTY LIST AGAIN?
HO HO HO!
to the number 1 club
in the world.
The potential of
Manchester United unlocked.
NYSE Euronext.
Unlocking the world's potential.
>>
>> Bill: AND BY ALMOST EVERY
MEASURE, TRADITIONAL FORCES IN
AMERICA ARE UNDER SIEGE DESPITE
WHAT BOB BECKEL SAYS.
HOW SHOULD INDIVIDUAL AMERICANS
REACT TO THATRO ON BOTH SIDES.
JOINING US NOW IS LAURA
INGRAHAM.
YOU HEARD MY TALKING POINTS AND
YOU HEARD BOB IN THE DISCUSSION.
GO.
ALL, DIDFIRST OF
PERINO AND GUTFELD PUT BECKEL'S
HEAD IN SOME TYPE OF VISE AND
SQUEEZE IT?
WHAT'S GOING ON.
THERE'S NO PROBLEM WITH
CHRISTMAS.
THERE'S NO ATTACKS ON RELIGION
IN THE PUBLIC SQUARE.
SUSAN RICE WAS TREATED UNFAIRLY.
WE'RE LIVING IN A PARALLEL
UNIVERSE.
LOOK.
MOST PEOPLE REALIZE AFTER THE
ELECTION AS OFTEN HAPPENS IN
POLITICS, THE SIDE THAT WINS,
THE DEMOCRATS, FEEL VERY HEADY.
THEY'RE VERY COCKY.
THEY FEEL THAT THE COUNTRY HAS
SHIFTED SO B MUCH BOTH POLITICAY
ANDRA CULTURALLY THAT THEY CAN
PUSH ALL OF THESE ISSUES.
>> Bill: AND THEY ARE.
>> THEY CAN PUSH MORE BENEFITS
FOR ILLEGAL IMMIGRANTS.
THEY CAN TAKE THE FIGHT AGAINST
RELIGION AND CHRISTMAS AND DO A
VARIETY OF THINGS.
THE PROBLEM WITH THAT IN THE
END, BILL, IS IT'S ALMOST ALWAYS
OVERREACHING ON THE PART OF THE
-- OF THE COCKY PARTY, THE CON
SEATED PARTY.
IN THIS CASE, OF COURSE, IT'S
THE DEMOCRATS AND MORE LIBERAL
DEMOCRATS.
THEY OVERREACH.
AMERICA KIND OF BRISTLELES BRISD
PEOPLE INVARIABLY SAY WHOA,
WHOA, WHOA.
MAYBE WE DIDN'T LIKE ROMNEY SO
MUCH, MAYBE WE WEREN'T EXCITED
ABOUT HIM, BUT WE'RE NOT THIS,
EITHER.
TAKE IT SLOW, LET US LIVE OUR
LIVES AND DON'T TRY TO PUSH
TRADITION OUT OF ALL ASPECTS OF
THE AMERICAN CULTURE.
I THINK DEMOCRATS ARE AT. RISK F
DOING THATIS ONCE AGAIN.
>> Bill: OKAY.
THE PROBLEM IS THAT IF I WERE A
SECULAR PROGRESSIVE.
>> YEAH.
>> Bill: AND I WAS ON THAT SIDE,
I WOULD PUT THE PEDAL TO THE
MEDAL BECAUSE THE OPPOSITION IS
SCATTERE
D NOW.
THE REPUBLICAN PARTY HAS TO
REORGANIZE.
OLD LEADERSHIP IS OUT, NEW
LEADERSHIP HAS TO COME BACK IN.
RATINGS FOR A LOT OF THE
CONSERVATIVE PEOPLEHE ARE DOWN,
PARTICULARLY THOSE PEOPLE WHO
BACKED ROMNEY BIG TIMEN. AND SAD
HE WAS GOING TO WOMIN THE
ELECTION, AND PEOPLE HAVE FLED.
THEY'RE CONFUSED, SO IF I'M A
SECULAR PROGRESSIVE AND YOU SAY
LOOK, HARRY BELAFONTE COMING OUT
AND I DON'T KNOW WHETHER HE WAS
KIDDING OR NOT.
HE WASN'T SMILING.
>> HE'S A COMMITTED LEFTIST.
HE WASN'T JOKING.
>> Bill: WHEN HE SAYS HEY, IF
YOU DON'T AGREE WITH THE DESIRE
OF THE AMERICAN PEOPLE, ALL
RIGHT, YOU KNOW, WE HAVE A JAIL
CELL FOR YOU.
YOU KNOW, WE'RE GETTING REALLY
NOW INTO A PRETTY INTERESTING
SITUATION HERE.
>> THAT'S LIKE JEFFREY SAYING
KIND OFT PRAISING CHINA RECENTLY
BECAUSE THEY CAN MAKE SOME GOOD
BUSINESS DECISIONS FOR
THEMSELVES, SO THE WHOLE SYSTEM
MIGHT BE SOMEWHAT ADMIRABLE.
THEY'RE ALWAYS JOKING WHEN THEY
SAY SOMETHING OUTRAGEOUS.
I THINK THEY'RE REVEALING IN
MANY WAYS WHAT THEY REALLY
THINK.
IT WASN'T TOO MANY YEARS AGO,
BILL, THAT YOU AND I WERE
TALKING ABOUTER HARRY'S COMMENTS
ABOUT CONDOLEEZA RICE AND EVEN
COLIN POWELL WHERE THEY LIVE IN
THE HOUSE OFEN THE MASTER.
>> Bill: RIGHT.
>> HE WASN'T JOKING THEN.
YOU KNOW, HE MAYBE OVERSTATED A
LITTLE BIT FOR HIM.
>> Bill: LOOK.
NOBODY CARES ABOUT HARRY ANYWAY.
>> THAT SONG IS IN MY HEAD.
YOU'RE RUINING THE CHRISTMAS
SEASON, THE BANANA BOAT SONG.
>> Bill: I LIKE THAT SONG.
>> WOULD YOU SING IT FOR US?
>> I USED HIM NOT BECAUSE HE HAS
CREDIBILITY AND THAT HE'S
SOMEBODY THAT PEOPLE LISTEN TO.
BUT TO GIVE YOU AN EXAMPLE OF
WHAT IS BEING SAID IN THE
SALONS, AT THE HUFFINGTON POST.
THERE ARESE PEOPLE GOING YOU KNW
WHAT?
IF YOU OPPOSE PRESIDENT OBAMA
NOW ANDEN YOU OPPOSE THE SECULAR
PROGRESSIVE AGENDA, WE'RE GOING
TO DEAL WITH YOU.
LOOK.
THE ATTACKS ON ME, I HAVE A
STACK OF NEWS CLIPS ALL OVER THE
COUNTRY BECAUSE HOW DARE
O'REILLY, HOW DARE HE STAND IN
OUR WAY AND POINT THESE THINGS
OUT?
WE'RE GOING AFTER HIM.
>> WELL, NO.
ANYONE OR ANY INSTITUTION OR ANY
MEDIA SOURCE THAT ACTUALLY
EXPOSES WHAT THEY REALLY THINK
OR EVEN QUESTIONS THEM, HOW
DAIRY YOU DO ADAREYOU DO THAT?
THIS IS HATE SPEECH.
IF YOU QUESTION ANYONE FROM
KANYE WEST TO BELAFONTE OR THE
CRAZIES, YOU'RE SOMEHOW
ILLEGITIMATE.
I KNOW HE WHAT THEY'RE DOING.
I'M NOT NECESSARILY BLAMING THEM
BECAUSE THAT'S WHO THEY ARE.
THEY DON'T LIKE, YOU KNOW,
SOCIAL. CONSERVATIVES.
THEY DON'T MUCH LIKE FISCAL
CONSERVATIVES.
THEY THINK THEY'RE SCARIER,
FRANKLY, THAN AL-QAEDA.
>> Bill: THEY DON'T LIKE
CHRISTIAN PEOPLE WHO SAY THIS IS
WHAT I BELIEVE.
>> RIGHT.
SOCIAL CONSERVATIVE CHRISTIANS.
>> Bill: THAT I BELIEVE IN
MARRIAGE.
THAT'S NOT A CAUSEE OF MIND.
I DON'T THINK THAT'S GOING TO
ERODE IF THE SUPREME COURT RULES
ON IT.
IT WOFON'T ERODE THE FABRIC OF E
COUNTRY.
I UNDERSTAND WHY SOME RELIGIOUS
PEOPLE AND TRADITIONAL AMERICANS
SAY YOU KNOW WHAT?
IT'S NOT THE SAME COUNTRY. W
IT'S NOT WHAT WE WERE BUILT ON
HERE.
>> I DON'T THINK WHAT'S
HAPPENING NOW IS D THAT THOSE
PEOPLE ARE DEMONIZED AS HATERS,
AS  TERRIBLE PEOPLE, THEY'RE NOT
LOVING OR COMPASSIONATE WHEN
THEY MIGHT HAVE A DEEPLY HELD
RELIGIOUS BELIEF OR A MORAL
BELIEF THAT CONFLICTS WITH THE
KIND OF POPULAR CULTURE.
LOOK.
I DON'T BLAME THEM FOR BEING
VERY HEADY AND EXCITED ABOUT
THEIR POLITICAL OPPORTUNITIES,
BUT I CAUTION AGAINST WHAT MIGHT
HAPPEN.
>> Bill: IF YOU'RE ARRESTED IN
THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT, PLEASE
CALL HERE FIRST.
WE'LL BOND YOU OUT.
ME, TOO.
I'LL CALL LAURA IF I GET
ARRESTED.
>> THANK YOU.
I'LL BE THERE FOR YOU,  O'REILL.
>> Bill: WE WOULD LIKE YOU TO
KNOW
LAURA SIGNED A NEW RADIO
DEAL STARTING JANUARY 2nd.
LAURA IS IN GOOD HANDS.
WE'D LIKEIS YOU TO VOTE AT OUR
BILL O'REILLY.COM POLL.
DO YOU BELIEVE THE FACTORS
CHRISTMAS CONTROVERSY COVERAGE
IS ACCURATE OR OVERBLOWN?
THE RESULTS ON
MONDAY.
>>> ASVE THE FACTOR MOVES ALONG
THIS EVENING, FEMINISTS
ATTACKING TAYLOR SWIFT AN AND KY
PEG EMBASSY.
>>KATY
PERRY.
>>> A U.S. MARINE ENCARS RATED
IN MEXICO FOR NO REASON AT ALL.
WE'RE ASKING THE MEXICAN
GOVERNMENT TO FREE HIM.
WE HOPE YOU STAY TUNED FOR THOSE
REPORTS.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Sharable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
YOU WON'T TAKE OUR FUTURE.
AIDS AFFECTS US ALL.
EVEN BABIES.
CHEVRON IS WORKING TO STOP
MOTHER-TO-CHILD TRANSMISSION.
OUR EMPLOYEES AND THEIR FAMILIES
ARE PART OF THE FIGHT.
AND WE'RE WINNING.
AT CHEVRON NIGERIA, WE HAVEN'T
HAD A REPORTED CASE IN 12EARS.
AIDS IS STRONG.
BUT WE ARE STRONGER.
AND AIDS...
♪
AIDS IS GOING TO LOSE.
ADT CAN HELP YOU
TURN ON A FEW LIGHTS.
ACCESS CAMERAS FROM ANYWHERE
TO HELP YOU KEEP AN EYE
ON THINGS.
EVEN BRING FAMILY IN
FROM THE COLD
WHEN YOU'RE NOT THERE.
NOW GET THE ADVANCED TECHNOLOGY
OF ADT
STARTING AT JUST $99
AND SAVE $300.
WITH ADT, YOU GET 24/7
FAST RESPONSE MONITORING
THAT HELPS PROTECT YOU
FROM BURGLARY, FIRE,
AND HIGH LEVELS
OF CARBON MONOXIDE.
PLUS REMOTE ACCESS
TO YOUR HOME.
EVEN CONTROL YOUR THERMOSTAT
TO HELP SAVE ENERGY AND MONEY.
GET ADT INSTALLED
STARTING AT JUST $99.
THAT'S A $300 SAVINGS.
YOU MAY EVEN SAVE UP TO 20%
ON YOUR HOMEOWNERS INSURANCE.
FOR EVERYTHING
THAT MATTERS MOST.
ADT. ALWAYS THERE.
Is bigger than we think ...
Sometimelike the flu.fer from
With aches, fever and chills-
the flu's a really big deal.
So why treat it like
it's a little cold?
There's something
that works differently
than over-the-counter
remedies.
Prescription TAMIFLU attacks
the flu virus at its source.
So don't wait. Call your
doctor right away.
TAMIFLU is prescription
medicine for treating the flu
in adults and children
one year and older
whose flu symptoms started
within the last two days.
Before taking TAMIFLU tell your
doctor if you're pregnant,
nursing. have serious
health conditions,
or take other medicines.
If you develop an allergic
reaction, a severe rash,
or signs of unusual behavior,
stop taking TAMIFLU and call
your doctor immediately.
Children and adolescents in
particular may be at an
increased risk
of seizures, confusion
or abnormal behavior.
The most common
side effects are
mild to moderate nausea
and vomiting.
The flu comes on fast,
so ask your
doctor about TAMIFLU.
Prescription for flu.
>> Bill: CULTURE WARRIOR SEGMENT
TONIGHT.
ALONG WITH THE RISE OF
SECULARISM IN AMERICA, MILITANT
FM NISM MAKINFEMINISM.
THERE WAS AN ARTICLE HARSHLY
CRITICIZING KATY PERRY AND
TAYLOR SWIFT.
APPARENTLY THE WRITER THINKS
THEY SHOULD BE, QUOTE, POWERFUL
MODELS OF MATURE WOMANLINESS.
HERE ARE TWO WOMEN WHO MIGHT FIT
THAT DESCRIPTION.
WHY DON'T YOU DEFINE THE POINT
THAT MISS PAGLIA IS TRYING TO
MAKE?
>> WHAT SHE'S SAYING, BILL,
THERE ARE WOMEN, SUCCESSFUL
WOMEN LIKE TAYLOR SWIFT AND KATY
PERRY WHO ARE IN THE FORBES
MAGAZINES THAT MAKE MORE MONEY
THAN JUSTN ABOUT ANYONE IN TERMS
OF, YOU KNOW, THEIR MUSIC, BUT
SHE'S SAYING THEY'RE INSIPID,
THEIR MUSIC IS BLAND, THEY'RE
MONOTONOUS, AND AT THE END OF
THE DAY THEY'RE TOO BUTTONED UP.
HER CONCERN IS THEY'RE NOT
TRASHY AND THEY DON'T REFLECT
KIND OF A SENSE OF REAL LIVING,
AND SHE TALKS ABOUT BLACK FEMALE
PERFORMERS AS STRONGER AND MORE
DEFIANT.
SHE IGNORES THE SUCCESS OF THESE
WOMEN.
SHE IGNORES THE FACT THAT PEOPLE
BUY THEIR RECORDS BECAUSE THEY
LIKE THEIR MUSIC, AND SHE
PREFERS WOMEN WHO APPARENTLY IN
HER MIND SHOW MORE BODY, MORE
BOSOM, MORE BOOTY, AND
THEREFORE, WE'RE GOING
BACKWARDS.
>
E SAMEl: DID YOU SEE IT TH
WAY, THAT ARTICLE?
>> I SAW IT AS AN AMAZINGLY
ANGRY FEMALEZI WRITING AN ARTICE
ABOUT OTHER SUCCESSFUL WOMEN WHO
SHE IS PROBABLY JEALOUS OF.
AND OH, BY THE WAY, BEYONCE,
TAYLOR SWIFT TO A CERTAIN
DEGREE, KATY PERRY ARE GOOD ROLE
MODELS.
IF YOU'RE LOOKING AT REALITY TV.
>> Bill: SHE DIDN'T CRITICIZE
BEYONCE, DID SHE?
YOU WOULDN'T DARE DO THAT.
>> NO, BUT TAYLOR SWIFT?
>> Bill: TAYLOR SWIFT 23 YEARS
OLD TODAY, I THINK SHE'S A GOOD
ROLE MODEL.
I THINK SHE TRIES TO PUT FORTH
GOOD THINGS.
KATY PERRY I DON'T KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT.
BUT PAGLIA WHO TEACHES AT
PHILADELPHIA AT SOME ARTS
COLLEGE, SHE WANTS THE WOMEN TO
DO W WHAT?
WHAT DOES SHE WANT?
WHAT'S THIS WOMANLINESS THING?
WHAT DOES SHE WANT THEM TO DO?
>> SHE WANTS THE WOMEN TO
UNBUTTON THEIR BLOUSES.
>> Bill: WHY?
FOR WHAT REASON?
>> SHE SAID YOU JUST AS WELL BE
BE TRASHY DURING THE DAY IF
YOU'RE TRASHY AT NIGHT.
OTHERWISE WE'RE REMINISCENT OF
THE 1950s WHERE WOMEN WAS
FOR THENT AND WAITING
MEN TO COME HOME.
>> Bill: SHE WANTS THEM TO BE
TRASHY?
DID YOU TAKE THAT AWAY FROM THE
ARTICLE?
>> SHE SAID GIRLS HAD TO BE
SIMPLE, PEP PEE, CHEERFUL, AND
MODEST.
>> THIS IS SUCH A SENSELESS
ARTICLE TO ME.
THERE'S SO MUCDEH MORE IMPORTANT
THINGS TO TALK ABOUT.
>> Bill: I KNOW.
THERE'S A BIGGER PICTURE,
THOUGH.
>> HERE'S PART OF IT.
WHO DOES SHE THINK IS A GOOD
ROLE MODEL IN THE SINGING WORLD?
MADONNA.
>> WE JUST TALKED ABOUT HER A
COUPLE WEEKS AGO AS NOT BEING A
GOOD ROLE MODEL.
>> Bill: MADONNA HAS A WHOLE
DIFFERENT POLITICAL AGENDA.
>> SHE STRIPPED DOWN.
SHE'S OBJECTING TO THE CLOTHING,
BILL.
>> Bill: I HAVEN'T BEEN O IN THS
THING AT ALL.
WEREN'T FEMINISTS AT ONE TIME
ANGRY ABOUT WOMEN BEING
OBJECTIFIED?
NOW SHE WANTS THEM TO BE?
>> I GUESS.
WE HAD DISCUSSIONS ABOUT HOW THE
NATIONAL ORGANIZATION OF WOMEN
WOULDN'T LET ME IN BECAUSE I WAS
A FORMER MISS AMERICA EVEN
THOUGH I WENT TO STANFORD AND
OXFORD?
THEY PROBABLY WOULDN'T BECAUSE I
WAS IN A BEAUTY PAGEANT.
>> Bill: NOW THEY WANT YOUNGER
WOMEN TO BE MORN E FLASHY AND
NOT GETTING ANY OF THIS.
>> I DIDN'T GET IT, EITHER.
>> SHE DOESN'T WANT THEM TO BE
MODEST, AND SHE DOESN'T WANT
THEM TO BE THE BLAND,
CULTIVATED, MIDDLE CLASS AIRLESS
GHETTO, SHE CALLS IT, GIRLS, AND
SHE DOESN'T MAKE -- SHE DOESN'T
HAVE A REAL CONCLUSION.
IT'S NOT -- THIS IS MY PREMISE,
ERGO.
>> Bill: YOU KNOW WHAT SHE
REALLY WANTS?
PUBLICITY.
>> MONEY.
>> SHE WANTS PUBLICITY.
>> Bill: SHE'S BEEN OUT OF THEN.
LIMELIGHT A LONG TIME.
SHE GETS THE HOLLYWOOD REPORTER
WHICH IS NOW SOME KIND OF LEFT
WING THING TO RUN THIS PIECE.
PEOPLE START TO TALK ABOUT HER.
THAT'S WHAT SHE WANTS.
DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE AT ALL.
PERRY AND SWIFT PUT OUT RECORDS
THAT PEOPLE LIKE.
THEY HAVEN'T DONE ANYTHING
OFFENSIVE TO ME.
I HAVEN'T SEEN ANYTHING THAT
THEY'VETH DONE.
ALL THEY'RE DOING IS MAKING AN
HONEST LIVING, AND NOW SHE SAYS
THEY'RE NOT WOMANLINESS.
IS THERE A WORD, WOMANLINESS?
I DON'T KNOW.
>> YES.
>> Bill: WHEN WE COME BACK,
PERHAPS THE MOST IMPORTANT STORY
OF THE EVENING.
A U.S. MARINE PUT IN PRISON IN
MEXICO FOR NOTHING.
THE MAN DID NOTHING WRONG.
MEGYN KELLEY ON THE CASE IN JUST
A FEW MOMENTS.
I HAD ENOUGH OF FEELING
EMBARRASSED ABOUT MY SKIN.
[ Designer ]
ENOUGH OF JUST COVERING UP
MY MODERATE TO SEVERE
PLAQUE PSORIASIS.
I DECIDED ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
♪
[ Spa Lady ]
I STARTED ENBREL.
IT'S CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO PROVIDE CLEARER SKIN.
[ RV Guy ] ENBREL MAY NOT WORK
FOR EVERYONE --
AND MAY NOT CLEAR YOU
COMPLETELY,
BUT FOR MANY, IT GETS SKIN
CLEARER FAST, WITHIN 2 MONTHS,
AND KEEPS IT CLEARER
UP TO 9 MONTHS.
[ Male Announcer ]
BECAUSE ENBREL®, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL,
EVENTS INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS, LYMPHOMA,
OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING ENBREL,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START ENBREL IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON ENBREL, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING,
OR PALENESS.
IF YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH, ASK
YOUR DERMATOLOGIST ABOUT ENBREL.
MONARCH OF MARKETING ANALYSIS.
WITH THE ABILITY TO IMPROVE
ROI THROUGH SEO
ALL BY COB.
AND YOU...RENT FROM NATIONAL.
BECAUSE ONLY NATIONAL LETS YOU
CHOOSE ANY CAR IN THE AISLE...
AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE
A FULL-SIZE OR ABOVE,
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
I'M GOING B-I-G.
[ Male Announcer ] GOOD CHOICE
BUSINESS PRO. GOOD CHOICE.
GO NATIONAL.
GO LIKE A PRO.
TIME FOR CITI PRICE REWIND.
BECAUSE YOUR DAUGHTER REALLY
WANTS THAT PINK CASTLE THING.
AND YOU REALLDON'T WANT
TO PAY MORE THAN YOU HAVE TO.
ONLY CITI PRICE REWIND
AUTOMATICALLY SEARCHES
FOR THE LOWEST PRICE.
AND IF IT FINDONE, YOU GET
REFUNDED THE DIFFERENCE.
JUST USE YOUR CITI CARD
AND REGISTER YOUR PURCHASE
ONLINE.
HAVE A SUPER SPARKLY DAY!
OK.
[ Male Announcer ] NOW ALL
YOUEED IS A MAGIC CARRIAGE.
CITI PRICE REWIND.
START SAVING
AT CITI.COM/PRICEREWIND.
CAMPBELL'S HAS 24 NEW SOUPS
THAT WILL MAKE IT DROP OVER,
AND OVER AGAIN.
♪
FROM JAMMIN' JERK CHICKEN,
TO CREAMY GOUDA BISQUE.
SEE WHAT'S NEW FROM CAMPBELL'S.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
>> Bill: I'M
>> Bill: WE'VE GOT A LOT TO TALK
BEGINNING WITH THE TERRIBLE
ORDEAL OF JOHN HAMMER.
HE'S NOW INCARCERATED IN MEXICO.
THE MEXICANS PUT HIM IN PRISON
AFTER HE REGISTERED AN ANTIQUE
GUN WITH THE U.S. BORDER PATROL.
THEN HE CROSSED INTO MEXICO.
APPARENTLY THE MEXICAN
AUTHORITIES SAW THE PAPERWORK
AND IMMEDIATELY ARRESTED
CORPORAL HAMMAR ON GUN CHARGES.
THAT WASCH FOUR MONTHS AGO AND
HE'S STILL IN PRISON.
SENATOR BILL NELSON FROM FLORIDA
SAID THIS.
>> BRING THIS MARINE HOME,
MEXICAN GOVERNMENT.
NOW THAT YOU HAVE A NEW
PRESIDENT JUSTICE INSTALLED IN
MEXICO, THE RELATIONS WITH THE
UNITED STATES ARE ESPECIALLY
IMPORTANT TO TREAT THE UNITED
STATES U CITIZENS WHO ARE PEACEL
IN THEIR INTENT, INNOCENT IN
THEIR OBSERVATION OF I THE MEXIN
LAWS.
>> Bill: HERE NOW ATTORNEY AND
FOX A ANCHOR MEGYN KELLY.
>> HE A WAS TAKING THE ANTIQUE N
TO COSTAR COAS COSTA RICA TO HU.
THAT WASN'T SMART.
IF YOU GON' TO MEXICO, DON'T TAE
ANYTHING, FLY TO YOUR RESORT
HOTEL AND GET OUT.
>> YOU HAVE TO THINK DON'T
BOTHER GOING UNTIL MR. HAMMAR
GETS OUT OF PRISON.
>> Bill: I DON'T THINK ANYBODY
SHOULD GOHI ANYWAY.
>> IF THE GUY SERVES OUR COUNTRY
AND GETS HONORABLY DISCHARGED.
HE UNDERWENT POST TRAUMATIC
TREATMENT BECAUSE HIS BUDDIES
GOT KILLED IN SERVICE.
HE HE GOES JUST TO HAVE A
SURFING TRIP.
>> Bill: JUST TO HAVE A LITTLE
FUN.
>> HE REGISTERS THE GUN.
HE'S NOT TRYING TO PULL A FAST
ONE.
HE REGISTERS WITH U.S. CUSTOMS
AND THE MEXICANS SAY THAT'S IT,
YOU'RE GOING IMMEDIATELY TO
JAIL.
HERE'S THE IRONY.
WHAT HAS OUR STATE DEPARTMENT
DONE?
WE'VE MADE A FEW PHONE CALLS.
THE PARENTS ARE VERY UPSET THAT
THE U.S. CONSULATE HASN'T DONE
MORE.
TYPICALLY THE WAY THIS WORKS IS
OUR STATE DEPARTMENT CALLS THEIR
STATE DEPARTMENT AND IT FUNNELS
ON DOWN THE LINE UNTIL IT GETS
TO THE LOCAL POLICE AND THEY SAY
DON'T BE RIDICULOUS.
THIS ISN'T ONE OF THOSE
SITUATIONS WHERE SOMEBODY GOES
HIKING OVER AND ACCIDENTALLY
CROSSES INTO IRAN.
THIS IS MEXICO.
THAT'S AN ALLY OF OURS.
WE GIVEIV THEM HUNDREDS OF
MILLIONS OF DOLLARS A YEAR,
BILL.
WHY ISN'T ITY JUST A PHONE CALL?
>> Bill: LET'S BE HONEST.
THEY DISRESPECT US ALL THE TIME.
NUMBER ONE, HILLARY CLINTON
SHOULD BE INVOLVED IN THIS
HERSELF.
WE HAVEN'T SEEN ANY SIGN OF
THAT.
NUMBERAT TWO.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SHOULD BEAM
INVOLVED.
WE HAVEN'T SEEN AT NY SIGN OF
THAT.
NUMBER THREE.
THE NEW MEXICO CA NEW MEXICAN P,
THERE'S NO WAY THIS GUY
SHOULDN'T LET THIS MARINE OUT
TOMORROW.
CHRISTMAS IS COMINGOM UP.
WE CALL THE MEXICAN EMBASSY
TODAY.
THOSE PEOPLE ARE TOTALLY
CHAOTIC.
>> THEY'RE VERY BUSY.
>> Bill: THEY DON'T KNOW WHAT
THE HECK IS GOING ON.
THEY DON'T CARE.
NOW WE HAVE T TO SQUEEZE AND PUT
PRESIDENPRESSURE.
>> HERE'S THE IRONY.
LET'S LET THE VIEWERS KNOW.
WE HAVE A 1MENT 9 BILLION BILLIR
ASSISTANT PROGRAM.
WE'VE BEEN SENDING MONEY FOR
BLACKHAWK HELICOPTERS.
RECENTLY OUR EFFORT SHIFTED TO
MORE OF A LAW AND ORDER
ASSISTANCE PROGRAM, AND WE HAVE
HAD THE FORMER DIRECTOR OF
COLORADO'COLORADO'S PENITENTIARM
HAS TRADE MORE THAN 5,000
MEXICAN GEORGIA.
THEY'RE RUNNING MOCK TRIALS.
WE'RE GOING DOWN THERE TO HELP
THEM REVAMP THEIR LAW AND ORDER
SYSTEM AND THEY USE IT NOT
AGAINST THEIR CARTELS BUT
AGAINST OUR MARINES.
>> Bill: HIS PARENTS WILL BE ON
HANNITY.IC
WE'RE GOING TO DO THE STORY
TOMORROW.
MEXICAN EMBASSY.
WE ASKED YOU ALL DAY LONG TO
COMMENT.
YOU'RE HIDING.
YOU CAN'T CONTINUE TO HIDE.
HILLARY CLINTON, YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU'VE GOT TO GET INVOLVED, ALL
RIGHT.
MISS SECRETARY, YOU'VE GOT TO
GET INVOLVED.
THAT'S IT.
IF PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS TO GET
INVOLVED, THEN GET INVOLVED.
THIS IS A MARINE CORPORAL.
THIS IS AN AMERICAN FOUR MONTHS
FOR NOTHING.
>> HE DIDN'T DO ANYTHING WRONG.
HE'S FACING UP TO 12 YEARS IN
PRISON, POTENTIALLY.
>> Bill: HE'S GOING TO GET OUT
SOON.
I HAVEVE CONFIDENCE THE NEW
PRESIDENT OF M MEXICO WILL DO TE
RIGHT THING.
>> IT'S A SKETCHY SITUATION.
THEY'RE CALLING THE PARENTS FROM
THE JAIL, TRYING TO EXTORT
THOUSANDS OF DOLLARS.
THEY HAD HIM MOVED TO SOLITARY
CONFINEMENT WHICH IS A SHED NEXT
TO THE PRISON GUARDS.
HE'S BEEN CHAINED TO THE BED.
WE WERE ABLE TO STOP THAT FROM
HAPPENING.
>> Bill: ENOUGH'S ENOUGH.
A SENATOR WHO HAD AN INTERN WHO
WAS IN THE COUNTRY ILLEGALLY,
AND A REGISTERED SEX OFFENDER TO
BOOT.
PICK IT UP.
>> WELL, THAT INTERN JUST GOT
ARRESTED.
KID.ONLY A YOUNG
HE'S. 18 YEARS OLD.
>> Bill: DO YOU KNOW WHAT THE
SEX CHARGE WAS AGAINST HIM?
>> NO, BECAUSE IT WAS
APPARENTLY.
>> Bill: SEALED?
>> IT HAPPENED WHEN HE WAS A
JUVIE.
IT HAPPENED HERE IN THE UNITED
STATES, AND YET WHY WAS HE STILL
HERE?
>> Bill: BECAUSE THEY DON'T
DEPORT PEOPLE, YOU KNOW.
>> THEY TAKE AN ILLEGAL
IMMIGRANT THAT'S A SEXST OFFENDR
AND GIVE HIM A JOB AS AN INTERN?
>> Bill: THERE'S AN ARTICLE IN
THE "BOSTON GLOBE" ABOUT ILLEGAL
IMMIGRANTS THAT COMMIT
HORRENDOUS CRIMES AND NOTHING
HAPPENS.
WE'LL HAVE THAT TOMORROW.
>> THE ASSOCIATED PRESS CLAIMS
IT HAS ONE U.S. OFFICIAL
FAMILIAR WITH THE CASE WHO IS
TELLING THE AP THAT ICE SNUFFED
OUT THE GUY, WENT TO THE
DEPARTMENT OF HOMELAND SECURITY,
SAID THIS IS GOING TO BE A HIGH
PROFILE THING BECAUSE HE'S AN
INTERN FOR A SENATOR.
THIS OFFICIAL CLAIMS HOMELAND
SECURITY TOLD ICE DON'T MAKE THE
ARREST UNTIL AFTER THE ELECTION
OCTOBER.HIS IS EARLY
ICE AND HOMELAND SECURITY ARE
DENYINGAL THAT ON THE RECORD.
THEY CLAIM NO POLITICS WERE
INVOLVED, AND THEY JUST MADE THE
ARREST.
MEES THEN DID H THEN DID HEMENEI
WAS SHOCKED.
HIS OFFICE SAID WE WOULDN'T HAVE
KNOWN HE WAS AN ILLEGAL
IMMIGRANT.
HOW WOULD WE HAVE CHECKED THAT.
>> Bill: AREN'T YOU SUPPOSED TO
CHECK THEUF RESUMES AND FIGURE T
WHERE HE CAME FROM?
>> I IT'S THE FEDERAL GOVERNMEN.
I KNOW HE WAS AN INTERN.
MAYBE ASK HIM.
>> Bill: RUN A LITTLE CHECK ON
HIM.
YOU'RE A SENATOR.
YOU RUN A CHECK AND SEE WHERE HE
IS.
>> THAT'S THE STATUS OF OUR
OFFICES ON CAPITOL HILL RIGHT
NOW.
>> Bill: MEGYN KELLY, EVERYONE.
KEEP YOUR EYE ON THIS MARINE.
>> HIS PARENTS ARE ON AMERICA
LIVE TOMORROW WITH ME.
>> Bill: YOU HAVE THEM, TOO?
WE'RE GOING TO HOLD THE
PRESIDENT ANDE  THE SECRETARY OF
STATE AND THE PRESIDENTSI OF
MEXICO ACCOUNTABLE FOR THIS.
THEY CAN GET HIM OUT TOMORROW.
>>WR> WATTERS WORLD ON DECK.
HOW MUCH DO THE FOLKS KNOW ABOUT
THE INTENSE DEBATE GOING ON IN
WASHINGTON?
WATTERS IS NEXT.
AND WE CAN SAVE YOU
10% ON GROUND SHIPPING
OVER THE UPS STORE.
LOOK THIS ISN'T
MY FIRST CHRISTMAS.
THESE DEALS ALL SEEM GREAT
AT THE TIME...
BUT LATER...
[ shirt ]
MERRY CHRISTMAS, EVERYBODY!
NOT SO MUCH.
HO HO HO!
THIS ISN'T
THAT KIND OF DEAL.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SAVE ON GROUND SHIPPING
AT FEDEX OFFICE.
to the number 1 club
in the world.
The potential of
Manchester United unlocked.
NYSE Euronext.
Unlocking the world's potential.
>> Bill: BACK TONIGHT.
WATTERS' WORLD, AS YOU KNOW, THE
PINHEADS IN WASHINGTON CAN'T GET
A DEAL DONE.
EVERYBODY'S TAXES MIGHT GO UP
JANUARY 1st AND SEVERE CUTS TO
FEDERAL PROGRAMS MIGHT KICK IN
AS WELL.
THE DEBATE IS FRAMED AS A FISCAL
CLIFF, BUT THAT'S A CLICHE.
THE REAL ISSUE IS FAIRLY
COMPLICATEDD MACRO ECONOMICS.
WE ASKED JESS JESSE WATTERS TO D
OUT WHAT FOLKS REALLY THINK
ABOUT IT.
>> THIS FISCAL CLIFF, I KEEP
HEARING ABOUT, WHERE IS THIS
CLIFF?
>> I ABSOLUTELY HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
I'M REALLY SORRY.
>> IT'S IN CONGRESS.
>> I HAVE NO IDEA.
I DON'T KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT
POLITICS.
>> PROBABLY IN BALTIMORE?
>> I DON'TTTI KNOW.
>> I THINK IT'S RELATED TO THE
MAYAN POPULATION.
>> DO YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENS WHEN
WE GO OVER THE CLIFF?
>>
YES.
OUR TAXES GO UP.
>> W THE MILITARY STARTS LOSING
MONEY.
>> YOU LIKE THAT?
>> I'M FINE WITH IT.
WE SPEND A LOT OF MONEY ON
THE MILITARY.
>> DEFINE THE FISCAL CLIFF FOR
ME.
>> F SOME IMAGINARY CLIFF
SOMEWHERE IN MY MIND THAT WE'LL
JUMP OFFEA OF.
>> YOU MEAN THE END OF THE WORLD
TYPE THING?
>> NOT REALLY.
[ MUSIC ]
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA AND HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHNJO BOEHNER HELPED
CREATE THIS FISCAL CLIFF.
IF THEY DON'T GET A LONG TERM
BUDGET DEAL DONE BY JANUARY
2nd, 2013, MASSIVE AUTOMATIC
SPENDING CUTS ARE TRIGGERED.
NOW, DO YOU KNOW WHAT THE
PRESIDENT'S PLAN IS TO ADDRESS
THIS CLIFF?
>> HE SAYS HE WANTS TO RAISE
TAXES ON ALL THE RICH PEOPLE.
>> EVERY TIME IT COMES ON THE
RADIO OR THE NEWS, I TURN IT
OFF.
>> RAISE TAXES ON THE RICH WHICH
I THINK WILL FUND GOVERNMENT FOR
LIKE AD WEEK.
>> ARE YOU WORRIED ABOUT YOUR
TAXES GOING UP?
>> NO.
I ACTUALLY HOPE THE FISCAL
FISCACLIFFHAPPENS.
LET'S DO IT.
>> DO YOU KNOW WHO JOHN BAY BOER
IS?
>> HE'S THE TAN GUY THAT CRIES A
LOT.
>> POOR THING.
>> MY BEST FRIEND.
>> I'VE SEEN HIM.
>> WE USE THE SAME TANNING BED.
>> THE FISCAL CLIFF.
>> YES.
ARE YOU AFRAID?
>> I'M VERY WORRIED, YES INDEED.
>> I'M SCARED OF HEIGHTS.
>> ARE YOU NERVOUS?
>> I THINK YOU'RE MAKING ME
NERVOUS.
[ MUSIC ]
>> JUST THE DAY BEFORE THE
PAINFUL SPENDING CUTS TAKE
PLACE, THEEF BUSH TAX CUTS EXPI.
THAT'S WHY THEY CALL IT THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WANTS TO LET
THOSE TAXES GO UP ON THE
SO-CALLED RICH, GENERATING $80
BILLION IN REVENUE.
THAT'S EIGHT DAYS OF FEDERAL
SPENDING, LESS THAN ONE PERCENT
OF OUR $16 TRILLION DEBT.
DO YOU KNOW HOW MUCH DEBT
AMERICA IS IN RIGHT NOW?
>> LIKE BILLIONS, LIKE 14
BILLION DOLLARS OR SOMETHING
LIKE THAT.
>> DO YOU KNOW WHAT OUR NATIONAL
DEBT? IS RIGHT NOW?
>> NO IDEA.
>> I'M GOING TO SAY 30 SOMETHING
TRILLION.
>> 16>> TRILLION.
YOU JUST DOUBLED IT.
ARE YOU A FACTOR FAN BY ANY
CHANCE?
>> I LOVECH YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> ANDHA I LOVE HIM, BUT I'M TOO
CHEAP FOR CABLE.
>> HOW ARE YOU?
I WATCH YOU ALMOST EVERY DAY.
>> I DON'T LIKE HIS COMMENTARY.
I'VE BEEN OUT OF THE COUNTRY TWO
YEARS.
>> LET ME GUESS, YOU'VE BEEN IN
FRANCE.
>> HOW DO YOU KNOW?
I NAILED IT.
>> Bill: SO YOU'RE ROAMING
AROUND DC AND I ALWAYS ASK YOU
THIS QUESTION, BUT IT'S
INTERESTING TO ME. WHAT, A COUPE
DOZEN PEOPLE?
>> ABOUT TWO DOZEN.
>> Bill: ALL RIGHT.
SO WHATHA PERCENTAGE OF THEM HAE
ANY INCLUD CLUE AT ALL WHAT'S A?
>> HALF OF THEM WERE TOTALLY
CLUELESS.
IT'S BECAUSE IT'S SO BORING.
NO ONE CARES.
THEY'RE TALKING ABOUT TRILLIONS
OF DOLLARS, AND THEY DO THIS MAN
WHO CRIED WOLF ALL THE TIME.
THEY HAVE THESE CLIFFS WITH THE
DEBT CEILING, WITH THE BUSH TAX
CUTS.
PEOPLE ARE NUMBER TO THIS.
THEY DO THIS EVERY CHRISTMAS.
THEY DON'T CARE.
>> Bill: LOOK.
NUMBER ONE, WHEN YOU SAY 16
TRILLION DOLLAR DEBT, IT DOESN'T
MEAN TO ANYBODY.
>> YOU CAN'T WRAP YOUR HEAD
AROUND THAT.
>> Bill: IF YOU SAID LOOK, IF
YOU DON'T MAKE YOUR CAR PAYMENT,
THEY KNOW.
>> THAT'S REAL MONEY.
>> Bill: NUMBER TWO, IT'S A
PRETTY COMPLICATED SITUATION.
IT'SUA NOT JUST RAISING THE TAXS
ON THE WEALTHY AND CORPORATIONS,
THERE'S A LOT OF OTHER STUFF
INVOLVED IN IT AS WELL.
OUT OF THE TWO DOZEN PEOPLE,
WERE THERE ANYBODY -- WAS THERE
ONE PERSON WHO REALLY HAD A
HANDLE ON IT?
>> WELL, WE RAN INTO AN ACTUAL
PERSON WHO WORKS FOR A SENATOR,
S -- THAT MADE THE
PACKAGE BECAUSE WITHOUT HER, NO
ONE WOULD HAVE KNOWN WHAT'S
GOING ON.
>> ONE OUT OF 20?
>> SHE'S A FACTOR FAN.
SHE ACTUALLY SAID SHE LOVED ME.
>> Bill: YOU CAN'T HAVE
EVERYTHING.
JESSE WATTERS, EVERYBODY.
HE'S THGOING TO HAWAII.
WATTERS IS GOING TO HAWAII
BECAUSE THE PRESIDENT IS
VACATIONING THERE.
>> THAT'S
RIGHT.
>> Bill: I'M SURE THE PRESIDENT
WILL INVITE YOU.
YOU'LL BE OUT AND IN WHY KEY KE.
THE TIP IS IN A 6 60 SECONDS AW.
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Sharable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>> Bill: FACTROR TIP OF THE DAY.
IT'S AN AMAZING SITUATION.
LOOK AT THIS FULL PAGE AD IN THE
"NEW YORK TIMES" TODAY.
CELEBRATING THE FACT THAT
KILLING KENNEDY IS THE NUMBER
ONE NON-FICTION SELLING BOOK IN
THE COUNTRY, KILLING LINCOLN,
NUMBER TWO AFTER 62 WEEKS IN THE
MARKETPLACE.NG
THAT HAS NEVER HAPPENED BEFORE
IN PUBLISHING HISTORY IN THE
UNITED STATES AS FAR AS WE KNOW.
ALSO THE KILLING KENNEDY AUDIO
BOOK, TONP SELLER THIS YEAR.
THE KIDS BOOK LINCOLN'S LAST
DAYS IS NUMBER ONE.
TRULYIO INCREDIBLE.
THANK YOU ALL.
TO THE MAIL.
STEVE FROM
WASHINGTON.
BILL, OF COURSE
THE NETWORK NEWS
DID NOT SHOW THE VIOLENCE IN
MICHIGAN.
THEY'RE ALL UNION MEMBERS.
I'M A PROUD UNION MEMBER, STEVE.
DOESN'T MAKE ANY SLANT STORIES.
THERE'S NO EXECUTE FOR IT.
FRANK FROM THE PACIFIC.
I'M A PROUD UNION MEMBER AND
DEEMPLOYER WHAT HAPPENED IN
MICHIGAN.
BILL, YOUR GUEST DEFENDING THE
UNION VIOLENCE WAS IRRITATING.
PLEASE LET LIBERALS DO THEIR
THINGS ON MSNBC.
I WANT TO HEAR THE OPPOSING
POINTS OF VIEW.
IT'S BORING.
THAT'S WHY WE MAINTAIN OUR
NUMBER ONE STATUS ON THE FACTOR.
WE EMBRACE ROBUST DEBATE.
>> AS A PRINT JOURNALIST FOR
MORE THAN 50 YEARS, I AGREE YOU
HAVE TO COVER VIOLENT PROTESTS.
GLENN FROM OREGON.
I AGREE WITH MILLER.
PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS MADE IT
CLEAR HE DOESN'T LIKE HALF THE
COUNTRY.
KATHY FROM NEW MEXICO.
I AM TIRED OF MILLER RUNNING
DOWN AMERICA.
WE REMAIN A GREAT NATION WITH
OPPORTUNITY EVERYWHERE.
ALBERTO FROM MEXICO.
O'REILLY, YOU AND MILLER ARE THE
MOST UNFASCINATING PEOPLE IN
AMERICA.
DANIEL FROM PENNSYLVANIA.
JUST WATCHED THE BOLDER, FRESHER
DVD.
IT'S SELLING BRISKLY ON BILL
O'REILLY.COM FOR CHRISTMAS.
CATCH US IN PERSON IF YOU CAN,
DAN.
IT'S WILD.
DETAILS ON THE SHOWS ON
BILLOREILLY.COM.
CALVIN FROM NEW YORK.
BILL, LOVE THE SEGMENT WITH
BARBARA WALTERS.
YOU GIVE HER THE BUSINESS, SHE
GIVES IT RIGHT BACK.
JENNIFER FROM CALIFORNIA.
O'REILLY, I DO NOT THINK BAR RAA
LIKES YOU.
LET'S BE HONEST, JENNIFER.
WHO DOES?
DIANE FROM CALIFORNIA.
HEY, BILL, BARBARA WISHED YOU
HAPPY HOLIDAYS.
WHY DIDN'T YOU WISH HER MERRY
CHRISTMAS.
WATCHING THE FACTOR AT HAPPY
HOUR?
DOING?E YOU
>> YOUR MERRY CHRISTMAS REPLY TO
BARBARA WAS PERFECT.
SEE THERE, DIANE.
DOUG GOT IT, YOU MISSED IT.
>>> A REMINDER.
THE SOTHEBY'S AUCTION HOUSE
TOMORROW WILL SELL THIS POSTER
TO BENEFIT THE WOUNDED WARRIORS
FOUNDATION.
ALL FIVE LIVING PRESIDENTS
SIGNED IT IT'S EXTREMELY
VALUABLE BUT MOST IMPORTANTLY,
ITT WILL HELP OUR MILITARY PEOPE
WHO BADLY NEED HELP.
YOU GUYS WHO CAN AFFORD IT OUT
THERE, YOU GUYS AND GALLONS,
THIS IS A TREMENDOUS HISTORICAL
ARTIFACT, ONE OF A KIND.
ACTUALLY, THERE ARE THREE IN THE
WORLD BECAUSE WE'VE GOT THREE OF
THEM SIGNEDE  BY ALL FIVE.
THAT'S IT.
NEVER GOING TO HAPPEN AGAIN.
SO CHECK OUT SOTHEBY'S.COM, THE
AUCTION IS TOMORROW, AND
OBVIOUSLY WE WANT TO RAISE AS
MUCH MONEY AS POSSIBLE FOR THE
WARRIORS, OKAY?
>>> THAT IS IT FOR US TONIGHT.
CHECK OUT THE FOX NEWS FACTOR