WHEN WE WENT OUT TO SEARCH, WE
TOOK THE ASSETS WITH TO US
ENSURE THEY WERE RIGHT THERE
IMMEDIATELY SO WE COULD REFACT
NECESSARY.
THAT IS ALL I HAVE AS FAR AS
THE DETAILS ARE CONCERNED.
I WANT TO GIVE YOU ONE MORE
BRIEFING, PROBABLY JUST BEFORE
6:00 TRY TO GET BACK UP HERE
FOR ONE MORE BRIEFING.
I'LL TAKE BRIEF QUESTIONS BUT
THERE ARE CERTAIN THINGS WE
CANNOT DISCUSS AT THIS TIME.
SIR?
>> DO WE HAVE ANYONE THAT
SURVIVED IT?
>> ONE PERSON WAS INJURED THAT
SUFFERED AN INJURY AND DID
SURVIVE.
>> CAN YOU CONFIRM A BODY IN
THE HOUSE WAS ADULT MALE?
>> I CAN'T CONFIRM.
I KNOW ABOUT THE SECONDARY
SCENE.
IT DIDN'T HAVE TIME TO GET IN
DETAIL ABOUT THAT.
I'LL TRY TO DO IT FOR 6:00.
>> I'M NOT CONFIRMING THE
IDENTITY OF THE SHOOTER.
WE HAVE A TENTATIVE
IDENTIFICATION.
WE ARE STILL WORKING WITH
THAT.
NOT GOING TO PUT IT OUT THERE.
HE I'LL IDENTIFY THE SHOOTER
AT AN APPROPRIATE TIME.
BUT FOR OUR INVESTIGATORTORY
PURPOSES NOT APPROPRIATE TO DO
THAT NOW.
>> WHAT IS HAPPENING WITH
HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY, THE
INVESTIGATION THERE?
>> IT'S PART AND PARCEL OF
WHAT WE DO.
I TOLD YOU WE WILL LEAVE NO
STONE UNTURNED AS WE LOOK AT
EVERY FACET OF THE
INVESTIGATION.
SHOOTER, VICTIMS.
WE WILL LOOK AT EVERYTHING.
WE WILL GO IN AND OUT OF STATE
AND WORK WITH THE FEDERAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT, INCLUDING THE
FEDERAL AGENCIES IF WE NEED
TO, TO ANSWER EVERY QUESTION
TO EXACTLY WHAT TRANSPIRED
HERE.
A TIME-CONSUMING PROCESS BUT
WE'LL GET IT DONE.
>> ONE SHOOTER?
>> YES, SIR.
[ INAUDIBLE ]
>> IT WAS K-4.
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADE.
THAT IS THE SCHOOL.
THEY WERE ALL STUDENTS OF THE
SCHOOL.
>> ALL IN KINDERGARTEN?
>> I DON'T KNOW THE GRADE THEY
WERE IN.
I DON'T KNOW THAT.
>> ONE CLASS?
>> ONE SECTION, TWO CLASSROO
CLASSROOMS.
>> I DIDN'T FIND IT OUT.
SORRY.
[ INAUDIBLE ]
THAT IS THE PROCESS.
THAT IS A GOOD QUESTION.
ARE THERE STUDENTS UNACCOUNTED
FOR?
WE HAD TO ENSURE WE ACCOUNTED
FOR EVERY STUDENT IN THE
SCHOOL, THAT INCLUDES SOMEONE
WHO WAS ABSENT FOR DAY BECAUSE
OF ILLNESS THAT DIDN'T COME TO
SCHOOL.
THAT IS PART OF THE PROCESS.
NOW WE HAVE THE IDENTIFICATION
PROCESS THAT IS MORE
DIFFICULT.
IT WILL BE SOME TIME BEFORE WE
CAN GIVE YOU THAT INFORMATION.
PROBABLY WON'T BE AVAILABLE
UNTIL TOMORROW.
>> CAN YOU IDENTIFY WEAPON?
>> WE HAVE SEIZED THE WEAPONS,
YES, WE HAVE.
>> WHAT KIND OF WEAPONS?
>> WE WILL NOT DISCUSS THAT.
[ INAUDIBLE ]
>> WE HAVE BEEN IN CONTACT
WITH ALL THE PARENTS.
WE WOULD NOT COME UP HERE
UNTIL WE HAVE BEEN IN CONTACT
WITH ALL THE PARENTS.
THEY HAVE BEEN FULLY INFORMED
AND THAT'S WHY IT TOOK SO LONG
TO COME UP HERE.
[ INAUDIBLE ]
>> THAT IS A GOOD QUESTION.
EVERYONE BELIEVES THAT, YOU
KNOW, IT'S SOMETHING THAT
FIRST RESPONDERS DO, THAT LAW
ENFORCEMENT DOES, WE PROVIDED
COUNSELING FOR THE FIRST
RESPONDERS BECAUSE THIS WAS A
TRAGIC, HORRIFIC SCENE THEY
ENCOUNTERED.
IT'S NOT SOMETHING WE WANT TO
SEE, NOT SOMETHING WE SEE
EVERY DAY.
THAT IS ONE THING WE HAD DONE.
THE COLONEL MADE THAT
PERFECTLY CLEAR THAT THE
PEOPLE ARE TO BE SPOKEN TO AND
RECEIVE CRISIS COUNSELING AS
REQUIRED.
>> LIEUTENANT, YOU HAVE TO BE
THE FACE --
[ INAUDIBLE ]
>> THE LIEUTENANT CAN TELL
YOU.
A NEWTOWN OFFICER.
[ INAUDIBLE ]
SURE.
>> THE FIRST THING I THOUGHT
ABOUT WAS MY OWN CHILDREN.
>> LIEUTENANT GEORGE SINKO.
S-I-N-K-O.
>> CAN YOU TELL US NOW --
[ INAUDIBLE ]
>> THIS IS MOST DEFINITELY THE
WORST THING WE HAVE
EXPERIENCED HERE IN TOWN.
TRAGIC.
RIGHT NOW WE'RE CONCERNED
ABOUT THE FAMILY OF THE
VICTIMS.
OUR OFFICERS ARE PROFESSIONAL
AND WE WILL DEAL WITH THIS AS
WELL.
>> DO YOU STRUGGLE GETTING
TOGETHER AS COUNSELING
SESSION?
>> THE LOCAL HOSPITAL, DANBURY
HOSPITAL, OFFERED THEIR CRISIS
INTERVENTION COUNSELORS.
THEY WILL BE AVAILABLE AT REID
INTERMEDIATE SCHOOL, ON
WASSERMAN WAY.
THEY ARE AVAILABLE RIGHT NOW
IF NEED BE AND THEY WILL BE
THERE ALL WEEKEND.
>> ARE THERE PARENTS GATHE
GATHERING?
DESCRIBE THAT.
>> THE PARENTS CERTAINLY HAVE
GATHERED AT THE LOCAL
FIREHOUSE, WHICH IS ADJACENT
TO THE SCHOOL.
WE HAVE DONE OUR BEST TO
COMFORT THEM AND TRY TO
REASSURE THEM WE HAVE DONE
EVERYTHING WE CAN.
BUT AS MENTIONED, IT'S A
DIFFICULT PROCESS TO CONFIRM
THE STATUS OF AN ENTIRE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE NEED TO BE RIGHT WHEN WE DO
THAT.
>> THIS IS HEALING.
WE HAVE TO THINK ABOUT THE
FAMILIES NOW AND DO EVERYTHING
WE CAN FOR THEM.
>> WE CAN'T CONFIRM ANY OF
THAT RIGHT NOW.
THE INVESTIGATION IS ONGOING.
>> ARE THE PARENTS FINDING OUT
NOW?
>> THERE ARE STILL PARENTS
THERE, YES.
I DON'T HAVE A NUMBER FOR YOU.
>> WHEN DID YOU REALIZE --
WHAT THE MAGNITUDE WAS, HOW
LONG DID IT TAKE YOU TO
REALIZE THE MAGNITUDE?
>> MINUTES AFTER OUR OFFICERS
WERE THERE THEY REALIZED WHAT
A HORRIFIC SCENE WE HAD THERE.
[ INAUDIBLE ]
>> I DON'T HAVE A TIMELINE ON
THAT.
THE OFFICERS RESPONDED
IMMEDIATELY.
AS SOON AS THEY REALIZED WHAT
THEY HAD, WE ASKED FOR ALL THE
RESOURCES WE COULD GET.
>> ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
>> WE'RE GOOD.
FINISH THIS.
WHAT WE'RE GOING TO DO, WE'LL
COME BACK JUST BEFORE 6 OF:00,
BECAUSE I KNOW OF YOU AROUND
6:00, GET BACK WITH ONE MORE
BRIEFING AND THEN WE'LL DO
SCHEDULED BRIEFINGS TOMORROW.
SOME OF YOU FOLKS LOOK TIRED
AND I'M SURE YOU WANT TO GET
SOME REST.
WE'LL SEE IF WE CAN GIVE YOU
SCHEDULED BRIEFINGS FOR
TOMORROW.
OKAY?
>> WHERE ARE YOU?
SHOW ME WHERE.
>>> THAT IS LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE OF THE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE WRAPPING UP THE LATEST
NEWS CONFERENCE IN THE TRAGEDY
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
HARD BITTEN OFFICERS, THEY'RE
DEVASTATED BY WHAT HAPPENED
WHEN THEY FOUND, WHEN THEY
WALKED IN TO AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL WHERE AT LEAST ONE
GUNMAN WALKED IN TO THAT
BUILDING AND OPENED FIRE THIS
MORNING.
26 INNOCENT PEOPLE ARE DEAD.
20 OF THEM CHILDREN.
I'M JOHN SCOTT.
THANK YOU FOR JOH JOINING US FOR
THE SPECIAL COVERAGE OF THE
BREAKING STORY.
THIS IS WHAT WE KNOW SO FAR.
IT HAPPENED AFTER 9:30 A.M.
EASTERN TIME AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AS CLASSES
GOT UNDERWAY.
FEDERAL LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICERS ARE TELLING FOX NEWS
THAT ADAM LANZA WAS FOUND DEAD
AT THE SCENE.
HIS BROTHER IS IN CUSTODY IN
HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY.
THEIR MOTHER FOUND DEAD AT HER
HOUSE IN CONNECTICUT.
THE F.B.I. CONFIRMS TWO
PISTOLS AND M-4 RIFLE FOUND AT
THE SCENE.
POLICE HAVE BEEN UPDATING
THROUGH THE DAY.
AND MUCH OF THE INFORMATION
HAS BEEN CHANGING FRANKLY.
THREE PEOPLE RUSHED TO THE
HOSPITAL, TEACHER AND TWO
CHILDREN ARE ALL EXPECTED TO
BE OKAY.
THE TEACHER WAS SHOT IN THE
LEG AND THE FOOT AND THE OTHER
CHILDREN SUFFERED NONLIFE
THREATENING INJURY.
GET TO SCENE WITH RICK
LEVENTHAL WHO IS THERE AND HAS
BEEN THROUGHOUT THE DAY.
RICK, DESCRIBE WHAT IS GOING
ON THERE NOW.
>> WELL, JOHN, WE HAD ANOTHER
BRIEFING FROM THE STATE POLICE
REGARDING WHAT THEY CAN TELL
US, WHAT THEY ARE COMFORTABLE
SHARING WITH US AT THIS HOUR.
REMEMBER THE SHOOTING WAS LESS
THAN EIGHT HOURS AGO.
THE INFORMATION HAS BEEN
CHANGING THROUGHOUT THE DAY.
BUT WHAT WE KNOW NOW IS THEY
GOT A 911 CALL FROM THE
SCHOOL, JUST AFTER 9:30 THIS
MORNING.
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT POLICE
OFFICERS WENT TO THE SCHOOL.
IMMEDIATELY CALLED FOR STATE
POLICE BACKUP.
WHEN THE REST OF THE OFFICERS
ARRIVED, THEY DIDN'T WAIT.
THEY WENT INSIDE THAT SCHOOL
LOOKING FOR CHILDREN, LOOKING
FOR ADULTS THAT COULD BE
BROUGHT OUT OF THE SCHOOL AND
BROUGHT TO SAFETY WITH THE
KNOWLEDGE THAT THERE HAD BEEN
A SHOOTING INSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
OFFICERS LOCATED TWO ROOMS IN
ONE AREA OF THE SCHOOL.
THAT IS WHERE THE 27 BODIES,
VICTIMS WERE FOUND.
TWO OF THE VICTIMS WERE
CHILDREN WHO WERE TAKEN TO A
HOSPITAL.
AND DIED AT THE HOSPITAL.
18 OTHER CHILDREN DEAD IN A
CLASSROOM.
FIVE OTHER ADULTS DEAD IN THAT
SCHOOL.
ALONG WITH THE SHOOTER.
26, THE SHOOTER.
20 KIDS GUNNED DOWN IN
CLASSROOM.
THERE WAS CONFUSION INITIALLY
ABOUT THE IDENTITY OF THE
SHOOTER.
I HAVE A APPARENTLY, THE
SHOOTER MAY HAVE BEEN CARRYING
HIS BROTHER'S I.D.
HE HAS BEEN CONFIRMED TO US AS
ADAM LANZA.
20-YEAR-OLD MAN FROM HOBOKEN,
NEW JERSEY.
HIS BROTHER, RYAN, AT THAT
ADDRESS IN NEW JERSEY, TAKEN
IN CUSTODY BY AUTHORITIES.
WE ARE TOLD RYAN LANZA
QUESTIONED.
ADAM LANZA THE SHOOTER WHO
KILLED HIMSELF AT THE SCENE.
WE ARE TOLD THERE IS A
SECONDARY SCENE IN NEW
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, POLICE
WENT TO THE SCENE, WENT IN THE
HOUSE.
AAPPARENTLY BACKED OUT AND
SENT IN A ROBOT AND LOCATED A
BODY IN THAT HOME.
THERE IS STILL CONFUSION ABOUT
WHO THAT PERSON IS WHO WAS
LOCATLOCATED IN SECONDARY SCENE.
WE HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE TO
CONFIRM.
I'VE BEEN TOLD BY SOURCES THAT
THE MOTHER WAS IN FACT KILLED.
WE CAN'T CONFIRM THAT IS IT
THE MOTHER'S BODY INSIDE THAT
HOME.
THE MOTHER IS A TEACHER.
APPARENTLY THAT WAS HER
KINDERGARTEN CLASS.
WE'RE HEARING THAT THE KID
WENT TO THE SCHOOL TO TARGET
HIS MOTHER AND KILLED EVERY
SINGLE KID IN HER CLASSROOM.
AS WELL AS OTHER ADULTS INSIDE
THAT SCHOOL.
HORRIFIC SCENE THAT PLAYED OUT
IN THE QUIET COMMUNITY.
60 MILES EAST OF NEW YORK
CITY.
IN A VERY AFFLUENT COMMUNITY.
THE FOLKS HERE ARE STUNNED.
THIS ISN'T THE THING THAT
ANYONE EXPECTS TO HAPPEN
ANYWHERE, LET ALONE HERE IN
THIS QUIET COMMUNITY IN
CONNECTICUT.
POLICE AT THE SCHOOL, STILL
GOING THROUGH IT, STILL
PROCESSING THAT CRIME SCENE.
IT WILL TAKE THEM DAYS TO DO
THAT.
>> UNDERSTANDABLY.
RICK LEVENTHAL JOINING US
LIVE.
THANK YOU.
WE'LL CHECK IN WITH YOU LATER.
JOINING US NOW IS BRENDA
LABINSKY, THE MOTHER OF A
STUDENT AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
ALL OF US AS PARENTS CANNOT
EVEN IMAGINE THE EMOTIONS THAT
YOU WENT THROUGH TODAY.
HOW DID YOU FIRST GET THE WORD
THAT THERE WAS TROUBLE AT THE
SCHOOL?
>> WELL, I WAS HOME, I
RECEIVED A SCHOOL ANNOUNCEMENT
CALL.
NORMALLY WE GET IF THERE IS
BAD WEATHER AND THE KIDS WILL
BE LET OUT EARLY.
IT'S, IT STATED THERE WAS A
SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN BUT DIDN'T
SAY THE SCHOOL.
OR IF IT WAS THE SCHOOL.
AND ALL SCHOOLS WERE ON LOC
LOCKDOWN.
I DIDN'T TAKE IT TOO SERIOUSLY
BECAUSE WE HAD SOMETHING LIKE
THIS HAPPEN PRIOR, BUT IT WAS
A SHOOTING ON THE STREET AND
DIDN'T HAVE ANYTHING TO DO
WITH THE SCHOOL.
BUT THEN I RECEIVED A TEXT
FROM THE A.P. THAT STATED
THERE WAS A SHOOTING AT THE
SCHOOL.
THAT'S WHERE MY DAUGHTER GIZ
AND I DROPPED HER OFF.
SHE IS IN THE THIRD GRADE.
I DROVE MY CAR AND SAW PEOPLE
I KNEW AND THEY WERE
HYSTERICAL.
I SAID WHAT HAPPENED?
>> WERE THERE POLICE THERE?
>> YES.
THE FIRE HOUSE IS BY THE
SCHOOL AND YOU HAVE TO PASS
IT.
THE FIREMAN WAS THERE.
NEWTOWN POLICE.
ORGANIZED.
BRINGING THE PARENTS AND THE
CHILDREN IN TO THE FIREHOUSE.
ALL I HEARD WAS A NEIGHBOR WHO T
AND SHE WAS DEAD AND SHE WAS
HYSTERICAL.
RIGHT THEN AND THERE I THOUGHT
OH, MY GOSH, MY DAUGHTER!
I RUN TOWARD THE SCHOOL AND I
SAW MY DAUGHTER'S FRIEND
KATIE.
I SAID WHERE IS SO FPHIA.
I SAID WHERE IS SHE?
AND SHE SAID SHE IS FINE.
AND SHE WAS WITH HER TEACHER.
>> THAT HAD TO BE A MOMENT OF
IMMENSE RELIEF.
>> YES, THE WORST MOMENT OF MY
PRIOR AND THE BEST ONE EVER.
BUT MY HEART GOES OUT TO THIS
COMMUNITY, TO THIS SCHOOL.
IT'S A WONDERFUL, CLOSE KNIT
SCHOOL, EVERYBODY KNOWS OCH
OTHER.
IT'S VERY SAD.
>> THERE HAVE BEEN QUESTIONS
THROUGHOUT THE DAY AS TO THE
IDENTITY OF THE SHOOTER OF THE
RIDGALLY IT WAS THOUGHT TO BE
RYAN LANZA.
IT TURNS OUT NOW POLICE
SAYINGITE TESS YOUNGER BROTHER
ADAM LANZA, WHOSE -- SAYING
THE YOUNGER BROTHER ADAM LANZA
AND THE MOTHER WAS TEACHER AT
THE SCHOOL.
DID YOU KNOW HER?
>> NO.
NEVER KNEW HER.
NEVER.
>> BRENDA, GOOD TO TALK TO
YOU.
I KNOW THAT WE ARE GLAD THAT
YOUR DAUGHTER IS OKAY BUT SO
MANY PEOPLE ARE SUFFERING
TONIGHT.
OUR HEART GOES OUT.
>> MY PLAYER GOES TO THEM.
THANK YOU.
>> OURS AS WELL.
BRENDA, THANK YOU.
SO 26 PEOPLE DEAD.
20 OF THEM YOUNG CHILDREN,
TRAGEDY THAT WILL RIPPLE FOR
WEEKS AND MONTHS TO COME.
WHEN WE COME BACK, THE
PRESIDENT SPEAKS TO THE NATION
ABOUT THE TRAGEDY.
>>> NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
POLICE DEPARTMENT RECEIVED A
CALL FOR HELP AT THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
THERE WERE FATALITIES.
THERE WERE 18 CHILDREN
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCHOOL.
THERE WERE TWO THAT WERE
TRANSPORTED TO AREA HOSPITALS
AND PRONOUNCED DEAD AT AREA
HOSPITALS AND SIX ADULTS
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCENE,
AT THE SCHOOL.
GOVERNOR'S REPORTED THE
SHOOTER IS DECEASED.
>> WE WERE JUST IN THE MIDDLE
OF GYM WHEN WE HEARD SOME
GUNSHOTS.
AND THEN THE POWER WENT OUT
AND THE GYM TEACHERS DIRECTED
US TO STAY AGAINST THE WALL
AND EVERYBODY STARTED TO KIND
OF PANIC.
>> WE HEARD A LOT MORE
GUNSHOTS AND THE AMBULANCE
CAME.
BUT THEN THE POLICE ADDRESSED
TO US RUN OUT OF THE BUILDING
AND GO TO THEMENT FOR.
THE FIRE DEPARTMENT.
>> IT DOESN'T SEEM REAL.
IT DOESN'T SEEM POSSIBLE.
YOU READ IT IN THE PAPER OR
SEE IT IN THE NEWS AND YOU'RE
LIKE MY GOD, THE POOR FAMILY.
THEN SOMETHING HAPPENED SO
CLOSE TO HOME, IT'S LIKE -- I
THINK I'M STILL IN SHOCK TO BE
HONEST WITH YOU.
>> WHAT HAS HAPPENED, WHAT HAS
TRANSPIRED AT THE SCHOOL
BUILDING WILL LEAVE A MARK ON
THIS COMMUNITY.
AND EVERY FAMILY IMPACTED.
I ONLY ASK THAT ALL OF OUR
FELLOW CITIZENS HERE IN THE
UNITED STATES AND AROUND THE
WORLD, WHO HAVE ALREADY
OFFERED THEIR ASSISTANCE
REMEMBER ALL THE VICTIM VICTIMSN
THEIR PRAYERS.
♪
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with uimited
talk and text.
by HTC for $49.99.
So we created the
extraordinarily
comfortable Sleep Number
Experience.
around a bed with DualAir
Technology that allows you
to adjust to the support
your body needs - each of
your bodies.
Our sleep professionals will
help you find
your sleep number setting.
Exclusively at a Sleep
Number store.
Sleep Number.
Comfort individualized.
This holiday season, give
the gift that's magical:
the innovative AirFit
adjustable pillow at
special 30% savings.
>> Jon: FOX NEWS ALERT.
MASSACRE AT AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN SANDY HOOK,
CONNECTICUT.
26 PEOPLE DEAD.
20 OF THEM YOUNG CHILDREN.
PRESIDENT OBAMA GETTING
EMOTIONAL AS HE ADDRESSED THE
NATION THIS AFTERNOON.
>> THIS AFTERNOON, I SPOKE
WITH GOVERNOR MALLOY AND
F.B.I. DIRECTOR MUELLER.
I OFFERED GOVERNOR MALLOY MY
CONDOLENCES, ON BEHALF OF THE
NATION.
AND MADE IT CLEAR HE WILL HAVE
EVERY SINGLE RESOURCE THAT HE
NEEDS TO INVESTIGATE THIS
HEINOUS CRIME, CARE FOR THE
VICTIMS.
COUNSEL THEIR FAMILIES.
WE HAVE ENDURED TOO MANY OF
THE TRAGEDIES IN THE PAST FEW
YEARS.
EACH TIME I LEARN THE NEWS, I
REACT NOT AS A PRESIDENT, BUT
AS ANYBODY ELSE WOULD, AS A
PARENT.
THAT WAS ESPECIALLY TRUE
TODAY.
I KNOW THERE IS NOT A PARENT
IN AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL
THE SAME OVERWHELMINGLY GRIEF
THAT I DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS
OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHER, MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES TO HELPING
OUR CHILDREN FULFILL THEIR
DREAMS.
SO OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN TODAY
FOR THE PARENTS, AND
GRANDPARENTS, SISTERS AND
BROTHERS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN.
AND FOR THE FAMILIES OF THE
ADULTS WHO WERE LOST.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN FOR THE
PARENTS OF THE SURVIVORS AS
WELL, FOR AS BLESSED AS THEY
ARE TO HAVE THEIR CHILDREN
HOME TONIGHT, THEY KNOW THEIR
CHILDREN INNOCENCE HAS BEEN
TORN AWAY FROM THEM TOO EARLY
AND THERE ARE NO WORDS THAT
WILL EASE THEIR PAIN.
AS A COUNTRY, WE HAVE BEEN
THROUGH THIS TOO MANY TIMES.
WHETHER IT'S AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN OR A
SHOPPING MALL IN OREGON,
TEMPLE IN WISCONSIN, MOVIE
THEATER IN AURORA OR A STREET
CORNER IN CHICAGO, THESE
NEIGHBORHOODS ARE OUR
NEIGHBORHOODS.
THESE CHILDREN ARE OUR
CHILDREN.
WE ARE GOING TO HAVE TO COME
TOGETHER TO TAKE MEANINGFUL
ACTION TO PREVENT MORE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS,
REGARDLESS OF THE POLITICS.
THIS EVENING, MICHELLE ANDLY
DO WHAT I KNOW WHAT EVERY
PARENT IN AMERICA WILL DO, HUG
OUR CHILDREN TIGHTER.
WE'LL TELL THEM THAT WE LOVE
THEM.
REMIND EACH OTHER HOW DEEPLY
WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
THERE ARE FAMILIES IN CONNECT
WHO CAN'T DO THAT TONIGHT AND
THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT NOW.
IN OUR DAYS TO COME THEY NEED
TO US BE AT OUR BEST AS
AMERICANS ANDLY DO EVERYTHING
IN MY POWER AS PRESIDENT TO
HELP.
BECAUSE WHILE NOTHING CAN FILL
THE SPACE OF A LOST CHILD OR
LOVED ONE, ALL OF US CAN
EXTEND A HAND TO THOSE IN
NEED.
TO REMIND THEM WE ARE THERE
FOR THEM, THAT WE ARE PRAYING
FOR THEM.
THAT THE LOVE THEY FELT FOR
THOSE THEY LOST ENDURES NOT
JUST IN THEIR MEMORIES BUT
ALSO IN OURS.
MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF
THE VICTIMS.
IN THE WORDS OF SCRIPTURE,
HEAL THE BROKEN-HEARTED AND
BIND UP THEIR WOUNDS.
>> Jon: CLEARLY EMOTIONAL
PRESIDENT OBAMA MAKING A
STATEMENT TO THE NATION THIS
AFTERNOON.
OUR CHIEF WHITE HOUSE
CORRESPONDENT ED HENRY WAS
THERE.
WHAT WAS IT LIKE INSIDE THAT
ROOM, SNED
>> Reporter: JON, THE
REPORTERS WERE TRYING TO CATCH
OUR BREATH.
WE HAVE BEEN COVERING THIS
PRESIDENT FOR FOUR YEARS NOW
AND NEVER SEEN HIM GET
PERSONALLY EMOTIONAL LIKE
THAT.
DESPITE MANY TRAGEDIES.
WE HAVE SEEN BEFORE, AS HE
HIMSELF NOTED.
THIS ONE HITTING HIM AND THE
NATION PERHAPS A LITTLE BIT
HARDER.
WHAT YOU DIDN'T SEE OFF-CAMERA
JAY CARNEY WHITE HOUSE
SPOKENSMAN SITTING A FEW FEET
AWAY FROM ME TAKING HIS EYE
GLASSES OFF TO WIPE HIS EYES.
THEY HAVE LOWERED THE FLAG TO
HALF STAFF AT THE WHITE HOUSE
AND BOEHNER HAS DONE IT AS
WELL.
PARTISAN OF RECENT DAYS MAY BE
SMALLER, THE FISCAL CLIFF
DISCUSSIONS INTERRUPTED.
THE PRESIDENT HAS NOW CANCELED
A TRIP HE WAS PLANNING TO
MAINE NEXT WEDNESDAY HE WAS
GOING TO PRESSURE THE
REPUBLICANS TO SUPPORT HIS
PLAN.
ALSO, WORTH NOTING WHEN THE
PRESIDENT TALKED THERE ABOUT
TAKING MEANINGFUL ACTION, HE
HAS BEEN CRITICIZED FROM THE
LEFT, AFTER SOME OF THE OTHER
TRAGEDIES.
FOR NOT GETTING SPECIFIC.
NOT TAKING ACTION ON GUN
CONTROL.
HE NOW LAID OUT A PROMISE,
BASICALLY, IN THE REMARKS IN
THE SECOND TERM HE IS GOING
TO, AS HE SAID, WE NEED TO
COME TOGETHER THE TAKE
MEANINGFUL ACTION REGARDLESS
OF POLITICS.
THE BIG QUESTION MOVING
FORWARD, THOUGH, MAYBE NOT
TODAY BUT MOVING FORWARD WILL
BE WHAT KIND OF ACTION WILL IT
BE, JON?
>> Jon: THAT IS THE
MILLION-DOLLAR QUESTION.
ED HENRY AT THE WHITE HOUSE.
THANK YOU.
SO CHAOS AND HEARTBREAK IN
CONNECTICUT.
TOWN LEFT TRYING TO MAKE SENSE
OF THE HORRIBLE TRAGEDY.
AHEAD WE'LL TALK TO BILL
HEMMER WHO IS JUST THERE ON
THE SCENE.
>> EARLIER TODAY, A TRAGEDY OF
UNSPEAKABLE TERMS PLAYED
ITSELF OUT IN THIS COMMUNITY.
LIEUTENANT GOVERNOR AND I HAVE
BEEN SPOKEN TO IN AN ATTEMPT
THAT WE MIGHT BE PREPARED FOR
SOMETHING LIKE THIS PLAYING
ITSELF OUT IN OUR STATE.
YOU CAN NEVER BE PREPARED FOR
THIS KIND OF INCIDENT.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] CAMPBELL'S
GREEN BEAN CASSEROLE.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO
[ "THE ODD COUPLE" THEME
PLAYING ]
HUMANS.
EVEN WHEN WE CROSS OUR "T"s
AND DOT OUR "I"s,
WE STILL RUN INTO PROBLEMS --
MAINLY OTHER HUMANS.
AT LIBERTY MUTUAL INSURANCE,
WE UNDERSTAND.
THAT'S WHY OUR
AUTO POLICIES COME WITH
ACCIDENT FORGIVENESS
IF YOU QUALIFY,
WHERE YOUR RATES WON'T GO UP
DUE TO YOUR FIRST ACCIDENT,
AND NEW CAR REPLACEMENT,
WHERE IF YOU TOTAL
YOUR NEW CAR,
WE GIVE YOU THE MONEY
FOR A NEW ONE.
CALL...
TO TALK TO
AN INSURANCE EXPERT ABOUT
EVERYTHING ELSE
THAT COMES STANDARD
WITH OUR BASE AUTO POLICY.
[ TIRES SQUEAL ]
AND IF YOU GET INTO AN ACCIDENT
AND USE ONE OF OUR
CERTIFIED REPAIR SHOPS,
YOUR REPAIRS ARE
GUARANTEED FOR LIFE.
CALL...
TO SWITCH,
AND YOU COULD SAVE HUNDREDS.
LIBERTY MUTUAL INSURANCE --
RESPONSIBILITY.
WHAT'S YOUR POLICY?
>> Jon: FOX NEWS ALERT.
SHOCK AND ANGUISH IN A QUIET
NEW ENGLAND TOWN.
GUNMAN OPEN FIRES IN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
CONNECTICUT.
26 VICTIMS KILLED IN THE
SCHOOL.
20 OF THEM YOUNG CHILDREN.
FEDERAL OFFICIALS CONFIRMING
THE SHOOTER IS 20-YEAR-OLD
ADAM LANZA.
HIS BROTHER ALSO REPORTEDLY
BEING QUESTIONED.
BILL HEMMER IS LIVE IN
CONNECTICUT WHERE IT ALL TOOK
PLACE.
BILL?
>> Reporter: GOOD EVENING.
WE WERE ON THE AIR ON
"AMERICA'S NEWSROOM" WHEN THE
NEWS CROSSED IT 10:30 EASTERN
TIME.
INITIAL REPORT CAME OUT A
TEACHER HAD BEEN SHOT IN THE
FOOT.
WE WENT A GOOD STRETCH OF
TIME, AS YOU RECALL, WITHOUT A
LOT MORE INFORMATION BEYOND
THAT.
NOW THIS PICTURE STARTS TO
COME IN FULL VIEW ABOUT THE
ABSOLUTE MASSACRE THAT HAD
TAKEN PLACE INSIDE OF THIS
TINY ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE THING THAT STRIKES YOU
ABOUT THAT PART OF CONNECTICUT
IS HOW BEAUTIFUL IT IS.
WE'RE A FEW HUNDRED YARDS FROM
THE SCHOOL.
BUT IMAGINE THE YOUNG AND
6-YEAR-OLD KIDS, THEY PLAYED
HERE.
THIS IS THEIR PLAYGROUND.
IN ALL LIKELIHOOD ON THE
WEEKEND THIS IS WHERE THEY
SPENT TIME WITH THEIR
FAMILIES.
THIS IS STUNNING TO COME TO
TOWNS LIKE THESE AND SEE
REACTION ON THE FACES AND IN
THE EYES OF THE PEOPLE YOU
COME ACROSS.
WE ARE AT A COFFEE SHOP DOWN
THE ROAD AN HOUR AGO.
WE MET A WOMAN WITH THEIR TWO
DAUGHTERS.
I SEE IN THEIR EYES.
I SAID HOW ARE YOU DOING?
THEY SHOOK THEIR HEAD AND SAID
WE'RE ALL RIGHT.
THE GIRL SAID, "TODAY IS MY
BIRTHDAY."
SHE ASKED ME IF IT WAS HER
9/11.
SHE TURNED 11 TODAY.
SHE WAS NOT BORN ON 9/11.
A TOWN UNDERSTANDABLY STUNNED.
JUST LIKE THE REST OF THE
COUNTRY.
>> Jon: YOU KNOW IT WILL BE
SOME TIME BEFORE THEY REOPEN
THE SCHOOL, MAYBE IF AT ALL.
IT WILL BE FILLED WITH
HORRIBLE MEMORIES FOR THE
CHILDREN WHO WERE THERE.
>> Reporter: JON, I TOOK A
WALK DOWN THERE A SHORT TIME
AGO.
THROUGH THE WOODS DOWN THE
HILL.
THIS WOODED AREA SURROUNDS THE
SCHOOL.
IT'S A TINY PLACE.
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADE.
IT APPEARED TO ME LIKE ONE
SINGLE BUILDING THERE THAT WAS
BUILT IN A SQUARE SHAPE WITH A
COURTYARD IN THE MIDDLE.
THE PARKING LOT IS NOT BIG.
RIGHT NOW, JON, THERE ARE
STATE TROOPERS, AND
INVESTIGATORS AND CARS THAT
FILLED THAT ENTIRE PARKING
LOT.
THEY HAD MENTIONED EARLIER
TODAY THAT IN ALL LIKELIHOOD
THEY WOULD NOT MOVE THE BODIES
FOR SOME TIME, BECAUSE THEY
WANT TO ASSESS THE CRIME
SCENE.
YOU CAN IMAGINE HOW GRISLY IT
MUST HAVE BEEN AS THEY FIRST
SAW THE CRIME SCENE.
BASED ON THE NEWS CONFERENCE
WE HAVE BEEN GIVEN SO FAR AND
TIDBIT OF INFORMATION THERE IS
SO MUCH STILL THEY DO NOT
KNOW.
>> Jon: THINK ABOUT THE
ANGUISH FOR PARENTS WHO KNOW
OR SUSPECT THEIR CHILDREN ARE
STILL INSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
THEY CANNOT HOLD THEM, TOUCH
THEM OR CAR RES THEM OR SAY
GOODBYE.
NOT YET.
>> Reporter: JON, YOU THINK
ABOUT CHRISTMAS DAY, TEN, 11
DAYS FROM NOW.
YOU KNOW THESE PARENTS ALREADY
BOUGHT PRESENTS, SOME OF THEM
PERHAPS WERE ALREADY WRAPPED.
NOW THEY DO NOT HAVE A CHILD
TO GIVE THAT PRESENT TO.
YOU HEARD THE ELOQUENT WORDS
OF THE PRESIDENT A FEW MOMENTS
AGO.
THAT'S WHAT SO MANY PARENTS
FEEL TONIGHT.
TO SEE THE KIDS IN PERSON.
TO GIVE THEM A HUG.
TO EXPRESS THE LOVE THEY HAVE
FOR THEM AND GRATEFULNESS THEY
HAVE TO BE TOGETHER.
DURING THE HOLIDAY SEASON.
SO MANY IN THIS TOWN DO NOT.
>> Jon: NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WHICH ONLY SAW
ONE VIOLENT CRIME REPORTEDLY
IN THE LAST YEAR.
NOW THIS.
BILL HEMMER ON THE SCENE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
LET'S TAKE YOU TO NEW JERSEY
NOW, WHERE THE SHOOTER'S
BROTHER REPORTEDLY LIVED.
ANNA LIVE IN HOBOKEN WITH
MORE.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL US WHAT IS
GOING ON THERE?
>> Reporter: JON, FOR PEOPLE
WHO ARE UNFAMILIAR WITH THE
GEOGRAPHY OF THE AREA, HOBOKEN
IS SOUTHWEST OF MANHATTAN.
THE BUILDING BEHIND ME IS
WHERE THE BROTHER OF THE
SUSPECT, OF THE NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, SHOOTING
REPORTEDLY DID LIVE AND WAS
TAKEN OUT IN HANDCUFFS EARLIER
THIS AFTERNOON.
THE STREETS HAVE BEEN BLOCKED
OFF.
CORDONED OFF.
THEY HAVE POLICE TAPE HERE,
KEEPING THE MEDIA AT BAY.
WE HAVE SPOKEN TO POLICE ON
THE SCENE.
THEY DON'T EXPECT A LOT MORE
TO BE GOING ON, ALTHOUGH IT
WAS LOT MORE OF AN ACTIVE
SCENE EARLIER TODAY.
THERE WAS ALSO SOME
PRELIMINARY CONFUSION OVER THE
IDENTITY OF THE SUSPECT IN THE
SHOOTING.
IF YOU WILL REMEMBER THAT,
EARLIER TODAY.
WE CAN TELL YOU THAT
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA IS DEAD
AND AUTHORITIES SAY THE
BROTHER WHO ALLEGEDLY WAS
HERE, 24-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZ RYAA
IS I CUSTODY.
THE HOME IS IN HOBOKEN, NEW
JERSEY, A TIGHT KNIT
COMMUNITY.
THEY HAVE BEEN SHAKEN BY THIS.
POLICE IN NEW JERSEY ARE ALSO
DEALING WITH SOME OTHER
THINGS, TOO.
THERE ARE REPORTS THAT RYAN
LANZA'S GIRLFRIEND IS MISSING.
ANOTHER FRIEND OF HIS IS ALSO
MISSING.
>> Jon: THAT IS INTERESTING
GIVEN WHAT WE KNOW ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED AT THE HOME WHERE THE
MOTHER LIVES.
THEY HAVE NOT IDENTIFIED THE
PERSON OR PERSONS FOUND DEAD
IN THE HOME BUT THE POLICE
HAVE A HUGE INVESTIGATION
AHEAD OF THEM.
WHAT ABOUT THE NEIGHBORS THERE
IN HOBOKEN, WHAT ARE THEY
SAYING?
>> Reporter: THEY ARE
COMPLETELY SHAKEN UP, BECAUSE
A LOCAL NEWSPAPER EARLIER
TODAY $IS A FLUID SITUATION.
REPORTS ARE COMING IN.
THEY ARE WATCHING IT UNFOLD
JUST LIKE THE REST OF US ARE.
NEWSPAPER REPORT CAME IN
SOMEONE WAS DEAD INSIDE THE
HOME.
SO, OF COURSE, THE NEIGHBORS
ARE VERY CONCERNED ABOUT THAT.
REPORTS THAT THE BOMB SQUAD
WAS GOING THROUGH THE BUILDING
AS WELL.
ALL SORTS OF JUST TERROR.
WHEN THEY ARE HEARING
EVERYTHING THAT HAPPENED JUST
MILES AWAY.
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
I DID SPEAK WITH THE FATHER OF
A LITTLE BOY WHO IS IN DAY
CARE.
THEY WERE ON HIGH ALERT,
BECAUSE THEY ARE IN THE AREA
AND NOTICED THE POLICE
ACTIVITY.
TAKE A LISTEN TO WHAT HE HAS
TO SAY.
>> OBVIOUSLY SCARY TO SEE
SOMEONE THAT CAN COMMIT SOME
ACT LIKE THIS IS LIVING
AMONGST YOU, YOU ARE WALKING
PROBABLY IN THE SAME
NEIGHBORHOOD.
I DON'T KNOW THE PERSON
PERSONALLY,BE BUT OBVIOUSLY
CROSSED PATHS FROM TIME TO
TIME.
THAT IS AWFUL.
>> THE NEIGHBORS THAT WE HAVE
SPOKEN TO ARE BANDING TOGETHER
AND THEY SAY THEY WILL COME
THROUGH THIS STRONGER.
NO DOUBT HAS THE COMMUNITY
EXPERIENCED THE TRAGEDY HERE
LATELY.
BETWEEN THE FLOODING FROM
SUPER STORM SANDY AND NOW ALL
OF THIS.
>> Jon: ANNA, THANK YOU.
>>> THIS EVENT WILL RANK AS
ONE OF THE WORST SCHOOL
SHOOTINGS IN HISTORY.
HARRIS FAULKNER HAS CONTEXT
AND JOINS US NOW.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
BEFORE I GO TO THAT, IF YOU
ALLOW ME TO, I HAVE BEEN
FOLLOWING OTHER DEVELOPMENTS.
THIS NOTE IN NEW JERSEY.
ANNA WAS TALKING ABOUT HOW ONE
OF THE BROTHERS, RYAN LANZA IS
IN CUSTODY QUESTIONED IN
HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY.
IN THE STATE OF NEW JERSEY, ON
TUESDAY, DECEMBER 18, THIS
COMING TUESDAY, THE GOVERNOR'S
OFFICE SAYS THEY WILL ORDER
FLAGS TO BE FLOWN AT HALF
STAFF.
N RECOGNITION AND MOURNING OF
THE VICTIMS IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
AND NOW THE CONTEXT, JON, THAT
YOU WERE TALKING ABOUT.
THERE IS NO WAY TO COMPARE ONE
HEART-BREAKING TRAGEDY TO
ANOTHER.
WE KNOW THAT.
AND ANY OTHER WAY THAT WE
WOULD DO IT IS MAYBE LOOK AT
THE PLACE IN HISTORY.
HARD TO CONCEDE THAT SOMETHING
COULD HAVE HAPPENED WORSE THAN
THIS SCENE.
FROM APRIL OF 2007.
A STUDENT KILLED 32 FELLOW
STUDENTS AND FACULTY, AT
VIRGINIA POLYTECHNIC AND STATE
UNIVERSITY IN BLACKSBURG,
VIRGINIA.
IT IS STILL THE WORST SINGLE
ACT OF GUN VIOLENCE IN
U.S. HISTORY.
AN THE ONLY SCHOOL SHOOTING
THAT INVOLVED MORE FATALITIES
THAN TODAY.
FOR SO MANY OF US TODAY WAS A
REMINDER OF ONE DAY ON
APRIL 20, 1999, WHEN THE NOW
INFAMOUS NAMES KLE BECAME PART F
THE AMERICAN DIALOGUE.
WE SUFFERED GREAT HEARTACHE AS
THE TWO STUDENTS OPENED FIRE
AND KILLED 12 OTHER STUDENTS
ABOUT TEACHER AND WOUNDED 20
OTHERS BEFORE KILLING
THEMSELVES AT COLUMBINE HIGH
SCHOOL.
LOOKING FURTHER BACK TO
HISTORY NOW, REALLY THE FIRST
TIME THE NATION DEALT WITH
THIS KIND OF VIOLENCE ON A
CAMPUS.
AUGUST 1, 1966, AUSTIN, TEXAS.
A UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS STUDENT
KILLED 16 PEOPLE AND WOUNDED
32 OTHERS IN AND AROUND CAMPU
CAMPUS.
AGAIN TODAY, NOW THE SECOND
WORST SINGLE DAY OF VIOLENCE
AT SCHOOL.
VIRGINIA TECH MASSACRE IN 2007
REMAINS ATOP THAT HORRIBLE
LIST.
JON, THIS IS NOT UNIQUE TO OUR
NATION.
YOU WILL REMEMBER YOU AND I
WERE ON THERE, REPORTING IN
JULY OF 2011, IN NORWAY, THAT
GUNMAN WHO SHOT AND KILLED AT
LEAST 85 PEOPLE AT A YOUTH
CAMP THERE.
BACK TO YOU.
>> Jon: SIMILAR EVENTS IN
RUSSIA AS WELL.
WHAT WOULD MAKE SOMEONE WANT
TO DO THIS?
HOW DO YOU HELP YOUR CHILD
DEAL WITH IT?
DR. KEITH ABLOW JOINS US AFTER
THE BREAK TO TRY TO ANSWER
THOSE QUESTIONS.
>> TEACHER, WHICH I'M SO
GRATEFUL FOR, THERE WAS JUST A
SMALL GROUP, THEY RUSHED THE
KIDS IN TO THE BATHROOM AND
THEY LOCKED THE DOOR.
AND THEY JUST TOLD THE
CHILDREN THAT IT WAS HAMME
HAMMERING.
TRIED TO KEEP THEM CALM.
THE NEXT THING I KNOW, BECAUSE
IT'S HARD TO GET A COMPLETE
STORY, THE NEXT THING I KNOW
IS THAT THE POLICE CAME IN AND
KNOCKING ON THE DOOR TO BE LET
OUT OF THE CLASSROOM.
WHEN THEY WERE, SHE HAD SEEN
GLASS AND BLOOD.
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
I HAD[ Designer ]EELING
ENOUGH OF JUST COVERING UP
MY MODERATE TO SEVERE
PLAQUE PSORIASIS.
I DECIDED ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
♪
[ Spa Lady ]
I STARTED ENBREL.
IT'S CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO PROVIDE CLEARER SKIN.
[ RV Guy ] ENBREL MAY NOT WORK
FOR EVERYONE --
AND MAY NOT CLEAR YOU
COMPLETELY,
BUT FOR MANY, IT GETS SKIN
CLEARER FAST, WITHIN 2 MONTHS,
AND KEEPS IT CLEARER
UP TO 9 MONTHS.
[ Male Announcer ]
BECAUSE ENBREL®, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL,
EVENTS INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS, LYMPHOMA,
OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING ENBREL,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START ENBREL IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON ENBREL, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING,
OR PALENESS.
IF YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH, ASK
YOUR DERMATOLOGIST ABOUT ENBREL.
>> Jon: 26 INNOCENT PEOPLE
SLAUGHTERED INSIDE AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
CONNECTICUT.
20 OF THEM CHILDREN.
TAKE YOU TO SCENE NOW.
RICK LEVENTHAL IS THERE AND
HAS NEW INFORMATION.
RICK?
>> JON, I HAVE JUST GOTTEN OFF
THE PHONE WITH A FEDERAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT SOURCE WHO HAS
KNOWN GIVEN ME THE TIMELINE OF
EVENTS, AS THE FEDS BELIEVE IT
WENT DOWN THIS MORNING.
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA LIVED
WITH HIS MOTHER HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WOKE UP THIS MORNING, SHOT HER
IN THE FACE.
THEN GOT IN HER CAR AND DROVE
TO HER SCHOOL, SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, WHERE SHE
WAS A KINDERGARTEN TEACHER AND
SHOT 26 PEOPLE IN THAT SCHOOL
BEFORE KILLING HIMSELF.
20 CHILDREN WERE AMONG THE
DEAD.
18 AT THE SCHOOL, TWO TAKEN TO
A LOCAL HOSPITAL WHERE THEY
DIED AT THE HOSPITAL.
AND SIX OTHER ADULTS KILLED
INSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
THEN THE SHOOTER APPARENTLY
KILLED HIMSELF.
BUT AGAIN WHAT I HAVE BEEN
TOLD IS THAT THIS KID, ADAM
LANZA, 20 YEARS OLD WOKE UP
THIS MORNING AT HIS MOTHER'S
HOME HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
SHOT HER.
THEN GOT IN THE CAR AND WENT
TO THE SCHOOL WITH THREE
WEAPONS, GLOCK, HANDGUN AND A
RIFLE DESCRIBED AS M-4 TYPE
ASSAULT RIFLE AND SHOT UP THAT
SCHOOL.
POLICE ARE AT THE SCHOOL NOW.
IT'S STILL AN ACTIVE CRIME
SCENE INVESTIGATION.
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE
DOCUMENTED, AND THEN THE
VICTIMS' BODIES RECOVERED.
THERE IS ONE ADULT RECOVERING
IN THE HOSPITAL.
THE SHOOTER IS DEAD.
THE FATHER APPARENTLY IS STILL
ALIVE.
I SHOULDN'T SAY APPARENTLY.
HIS FATHER I'M TOLD IS ALIVE
AND IS SPEAKING TO THE F.B.I.
AT THIS HOUR IN NEW JERSEY.
HIS BROTHER RYAN ALSO ALIVE
AND COOP RAIDIN COOPERATING WITH
AUTHORITIES.
NEITHER PERSON IS SUSPECTED OF
HAVING ANY INVOLVEMENT IN
THIS.
THE BROTHER ADAM DESCRIBED AS
TROUBLED IS THE SHOOTER
CONFIRMED TO ME BY FEDERAL
AUTHORITIES.
>> WE SHOULD POINT OUT IT WAS
REPORTED, QUITE WIDELY, THAT
THE FATHER HAD BEEN KILLED.
BUT AS YOU ARE POINTING OUT.
>> I'M NOT SURE WHERE THAT
CAME FROM.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE THE REPORT
THERE WERE REPORTS AN ACTIVE
SCENE IN NEW JERSEY.
THAT IS TRUE.
THE BROTHER IS TALKING TO
AUTHORITIES.
ADAM LANZA IDENTIFIED AS THE
SHOOTER.
KILLED HIS MOTHER AND WENT TO
THE SCHOOL WHERE SHE WORKED
FOR NO REASON AND SLAUGHTERED
PEOPLE INSIDE.
>> RICK LEVENTHAL, THANK YOU
FOR THE INFORMATION, AWFUL AS
IT IS.
THANK YOU.
LET'S CHECK IN WITH DR. KEITH
ABLOW, PSYCHIATRIST AND
MEDICAL A-TEAMER WHO JOINS US
LIVE FROM BOSTON.
YOU HEAR WHAT HAPPENED, DOCK
TOKER AND IT'S -- DOCTOR, AND
IT'S CONCEIVABLE.
IS IT MENTAL ILLNESS,
SOCIOPATHIC PERSONALITY?
WHAT ARE WE LOOKING AT HERE?
LOOKING AT SOMETHING DEEPLY
DISTURBED UNFOLDING HERE,
OBVIOUSLY.
IF YOU THINK ABOUT THE ACT OF
WALKING IN TO A SCHOOL AND
BEING UNDETERRED, BY THE
INJURIES, FATAL INJURIES THAT
YOU ARE INFLICTING ON ONE
AFTER ANOTHER CHILD THEN YOUR
CAPACITY TO FEEL FOR OTHERS IS
ENTIRELY SHATTERED.
WHAT WE CALL THIS WILL BE
DETERMINED IN DAYS AND WEEKS
TO COME.
WAS IT A DELUSION?
DID THIS PERSON THINK THAT BY
DOING THIS, HE WAS RIDDING THE
EARTH OF EVIL?
THAT IS ONE KIND OF ILLNESS.
WAS THIS PERSON IN SOME WAY
DEVOID OF EMPATHY BECAUSE OF
CHILDHOOD EVENTS OF HIS OWN?
DID KILLING HIS MOTHER REALLY
PLAY IN TO THIS BECAUSE OF
SOME HORRIBLE TURMOIL IN THAT
FAMILY?
BUT I WILL TELL YOU THIS, THE
BOTTOM LINE IS THAT WE WILL
FIND OUT, I WOULD PREDICT THAT
THERE WERE SIGNS.
THAT THIS WAS A DEEPLY
DISTURBED PERSON AND THAT THE
SIGNS SHOULD HAVE OR COULD
HAVE BEEN TAKEN MORE
SERIOUSLY, BECAUSE WE SEE THAT
AGAIN AND AGAIN IN THESE
INSTANCES.
>> Jon: BUT WHY THE
CHILDREN?
I MEAN, THE MOTHER WASN'T EVEN
THERE IN THE ROOM.
AS STRANGE OR TWISTED AS IT
MAY SOUND, I COULD IMAGINE
GOING TO THE SCHOOL IF THE
MOTHER WAS THERE AND THEN THE
CHILDREN BECOME, YOU KNOW,
PART OF THIS TERRIBLE SHOOTING
GALLERY.
BUT SHE APPARENTLY WAS ALREADY
DEAD.
WHY GO TO HER CLASSROOM?
>> IT WOULD ALL BE CONJECTURE
AT THIS POINT.
SPEAKING FROM A PSYCHODYNAMIC
STANDPOINT WHAT YOU HAVE
SOMEBODY WHO TAKES HIS
MOTHER'S LIFE AND THEN TAKES
THE LIVES MOF CHILDREN.
WERE HE HERE OR COULD WE SPEAK
TO HIS BROTHER WE'D SAY I WANT
TO HEAR ABOUT YOUR BROTHER'S
CHILDHOOD.
WAS IT MARKED BY TERRIBLE
PAIN?
IS THIS SOME KIND OF SYMBOL?
SYMBOL OF WHAT HE LIVED
THROUGH?
DID HE HAVE IT IN FOR YOUR
MOTHER'S JOB?
DID HE FEEL SHE SHOULD HAVE
BEEN PAYING ATTENTION TO HIM?
IRRATIONAL BUT THESE ARE
IRRATIONM ACTS THAT STILL YOU
CAN WRITE A STORY THAT
EXPLAINS WHAT HAS HAPPENED.
ONCE YOU UNDERSTAND HOW THAT
PERSON HAS BEEN THINKING.
MY GUESS IS THAT HELED
SOME OF THE THOUGHTS BEFORE
THIS.
AND WE'VE GOT TO GET VERY
SERIOUS IN THE COUNTRY ABOUT
TAKING THOSE THINGS SERIOUSLY.
AND KNOWING WHAT TO DO.
WE HAVE TO GET THE WORD OUT
ABOUT COMMUNITY MENTAL HEALTH
CENTERS AND POLICE AND THE
REST OF IT.
>> Jon: MENTAL ILLNESS.
DR. KEITH ABLOW, THANK YOU.
>> THAT'S WHAT IT IS.
>> Jon: ALL RIGHT MY FRIEND.
WE EXPECT TO HEAR FROM THE
CONNECTICUT POLICE AGAIN AT
THE TOP OF HOUR.
WE ARE AWAITING A NEWS
CONFERENCE WITH THE LATEST
INFORMATION.
WE'LL HAVE IT FOR YOU LIVE AS
SOON AS IT BEGINS.
Why is it that the
most impressive technology
often comes with a set
of equally impressive
instructions ?
Shouldn't something
that's truly advanced,
not need much explanation
at all ?
With the Nokia Lumia 822
on Verizon,
there's not much to learn
because it's
powered by Windows...
to let you do more than you ever
imagined on your smartphone.
Exclusively with Data Sense--
a feature that makes
the most of your plan.
Only on Verizon.
>> Jon: FOX NEWS ALERT, WE
ARE AWAITING AN HOURLY UPDATE
ON THE SCHOOL SHOOTING TRAGEDY
IN CONNECTICUT.
WE KNOW 26 INNOCENT PEOPLE
WERE KILLED, 20 INSIDE THE
SCHOOL.
18 DIED AT THE SCHOOL.
TWO WERE TAKEN TO A HOSPITAL
AND DIED THERE.
STEVE, A FORMER POLICE
DETECTIVE, A SCHOOL SECURITY
EXPERT JOINS US NOW.
HOW DO YOU STOP SOMETHING LIKE
THIS?
>> WE HAVE TO REVIEW THE
CURRENT SYSTEM.
IT'S NOT WORKING.
WE ARE PUTTING THIS IN THE
BRAINS OF INDIVIDUALS, TO
COMMIT THESE CRIMES.
OUR EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTION,
AT THIS LEVEL WITH CHILDREN
THAT YOUNG ARE SOFT TARGETS.
EVERY SCHOOL ACROSS AMERICA IS
A SOFT TARGET.
WE NEED TO REVAMP THE SYSTEM.
IF WE HAVE TO PUT A POLICE
OFFICER IN EVERY SCHOOL, WE
NEED TO DO THAT.
WE NEED TO TRAIN OUR TEACHERS.
THEY ARE THE FIRST LINE OF
DEFENSE.
WE NEED THEM TO STEP UP AND
ANSWER FOR THE YOUNG CHILDREN.
OLDER PEOPLE, WE CAN TELL
THEM.
BUT THE CHILDREN HAVE SEEN
DOZEN OF FATAL SHOOTINGS, NONE
OF THEM REAL.
THEY ARE OCCURRING ON TV.
THEY HAVEN'T GOT THE CONCEPT.
IT'S MANY YEARS BEFORE THE
EFFECTS SET IN ON THEM.
>> THE SHOOTERN'T GO IN A
POLICE DEPARTMENT, DOESN'T GO
TO A MILITARY BASE.
HE GOES TO WHERE THERE ARE
ABSOLUTELY UNPROTECTED
INDIVIDUALS, UNABLE TO FIGHT
BACK.
>> COWARDLY ACT.
EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTIONS ARE
SET UP SO THIS TYPE OF THING
CAN OCCUR.
WE HAVE SEEN THIS TIME AND
TIME AGAIN.
THE SCHOOL TEACHERS,
EDUCATORS, RIGHT NOW IT'S NOT
ON THEIR MIND.
IT'S NOT ON THEIR MIND THAT
THEY WILL HAVE TO GO TO SCHOOL
AND DEFEND THEMSELVES AND THE
CHILDREN'S LIVES.
>> THE WEBSITE SAID THEY LOCK
IT DOWN AT 9:30.
THE SHOOTING HAPPENED AT 9:40.
MAYBE A SLIGHT SLIP IN
BROTHERS AND MAYBE NOT.
APPARENTLY THE SHOOTER WAS A
SON OF ONE OF THE PEOPLE.
PROBABLY FAMILIAR WITH WHOEVER
OPERATES THE BUZZER TO LET
THEM IN.
>> AND A SOFT TARGET, SUCH AS
THE SCHOOL, I WOULD IMAGINE
THAT IF YOU REALLY WANT TO GET
IN, YOU ARE GOING TO GET IN.
MORE SECURITY, MORE
TECHNIQUES, IT'S GOT TO BE
EVALUATED.
IT WILL HAVE TO BE AT THE
HIGHER LEVEL.
PUT TOGETHER A PANEL OF
EXPERTS REVIEW THIS OVER ONE
PERIOD.
THIS REPORT IS GOING TO BE
EXTENSIVE.
>> Jon: I BELIEVE IT WAS
FORMER NEW YORK CITY MAYOR
RUDY GIULIANI SAID EVEN IF YOU
HAVE ARMED GUARDS AT THE
SCHOOL YOU'D PROBABLY WIND UP
DRIVING THE SUSPECT TO SOME
OTHER PLACE, WHERE THERE ARE
NO ARMED GUARDS TOX A SHOPPING
MALL OR A PUBLIC PARK OR
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
>> WHAT YOU MIGHT DO IF YOU
HAD AN ARMED SECURITY LAW
ENFORCEMENT PROFESSIONAL I
WOULD SAY THAT WOULD ENGAGE
HIM, IT WOULD GIVE
NOTIFICATION TO THE SCHOOL AND
WE COULD PROTECT OUR CHILDREN.
LOCK DOWN, GET THE DOORS
LOCKED.
YOU CAN'T, I DON'T CARE HOW
POWERFUL THE WEAPON YOU HAVE,
YOU WON'T SHOOT A LOCK OFF THE
DOOR.
SHUT THE DOORS HAVE THE BAR
INTERIOR, KEEP THE KIDS ON
LOCKDOWN UP AGAINST THE WALL.
LIGHTS OFF.
MOVE TO ANOTHER CLASSROOM.
THE MORE TIME WE HAVE, THE
MORE TIME TO GET LAW
ENFORCEMENT THERE, WHEN THE
SECONDS COUNT IT TAKES US
MINUTES TO GET THERE.
>> Jon: I REMEMBER BEING ON
THE AIR IN THE 9/11 ATTACKS
THINKING THIS IS A DAY THAT
EVERYTHING CHANGE CHANGES IN THS
COUNTRY.
IT REALLY DID.
YOU LOOK AT CREATION OF TSA
AND THE WARS THAT CAME AFTER.
IS THIS EVENT SOMETHING THAT
IS GOING TO BRING ABOUT
MONUMENTAL CHANGES, WHETHER
THEY ARE EFFECTIVE OR NOT, IN
SCHOOL SECURITY?
>> I AM HOPING THAT IT IS.
I BELIEVE IT IS GOING TO
PROMPT SOME CHANGES;  IS SUCH
AS, 9/11.
I AM FEELING THE EMOTIONAL
EFFECTS OF WHAT I FELT ON
9/11.
IT SPENT A WEEK DOWN THERE.
IT WILL PROFIT CHANGE.
JUST LIKE WE HAD VERY LENGTHY
STUDY, WITH VIRGINIA TECH.
THIS IS ALSO -- THEY WILL BE
THERE FOR A LONG TIME AND THEY
MAY NEVER GO BACK AND OPEN THE
SCHOOL UP.
>> Jon: BUT THE WORLD HAS
ALWAYS KNOWN MAD MEN.
IF THERE ARE ALWAYS MAD MEN IN
THE FUTURE, THEY WILL ALWAYS
FIND A WAY TO INFLICT CARNAGE,
ARE THEY NOT?
>> BEYOND COMPREHENSION,
BEYOND EEL.
WE CAN LEARN FOR IT.
YES, THEY WILL.
IF WE PROTECT OURSELVES.
REASON, OUR SCHOOLS, EDUCATORS
ARE THE FIRST LINE.
IF WE DON'T HAVE THE LAW
ENFORCEMENT THERE.
EVERY SCHOOL ACROSS THE NATION
HAS POLICY IN PLACE.
NOT GOOD ENOUGH.
IT NEEDS TO BE IMPROVED,
REVAMPED AND IMPROVED.
WE HAVE CAN'T LET IT HAPPEN
AGAIN.
>> Jon: BUT THAT IS EASER IS
SAID THAN DONE, ISN'T IT?
>> I KNOW.
IT'S NOT A SOLUTION THAT WILL
OCCUR OVERNIGHT.
LENGTHY SOLUTION OVER TIME.
THERE WILL PROBABLY BE MORE
MASS SHOOTINGS BETWEEN NOW AND
WHEN WE FIND A BETTER WAY.
>> Jon: YOU CAN'T PUT POLICE
OFFICERS FULL-TIME AROUND THE
CLOCK IN EVERY SCHOOL IN
AMERICA, CAN YOU?
>> WE HAVE SOME SCHOOLS THAT
DO THAT.
WHO WOULD THINK NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, SUBURBAN
COMMUNITY.
>> Jon: ONE VIOLENT CRIME IN
THE LAST YEAR, WE'RE TOLD.
>> WE AREN'T PREPARED AS A
SOCIETY TO DEAL WITH CARNAGE.
WE ARE NOT PREPARED TO DEAL
WITH THIS TYPE OF VIOLENCE.
WHEN IT HAPPENS, WHAT HAPPENS,
MOST OF THE PEOPLE FREEZE.
LOOK AT THE SUBWAY KILLINGS.
THE PEOPLE HAD NO CLUE WHAT
THEY SHOULD HAVE DONE IN NEW
YORK CITY.
>> YEAH.
>> Jon: JUST SO OUR VIEWERS
KNOW WE ARE STILL WAITING A
NEWS CONFERENCE EXPECTED NOW
AT THE TOP OF THE HOUR.
FROM THE STATE POLICE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WHERE
THE TERRIBLE SHOOTING
HAPPENED.
THEY HAVE BEEN UPDATING
REPORTERS FAIRLY REGULARLY
THROUGHOUT THE AFTERNOON.
AFTER A MORNING IN WHICH THERE
WAS PRECIOUS LITTLE
INFORMATION ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED THERE.
THE EARLY REPORTS INDICATED
THAT THREE PEOPLE MIGHT HAVE
BEEN SHOT AND TAKEN TO THE
HOSPITAL.
BUT THAT THERE WAS NO
INDICATION THAT BLOODBATH WAS
AS SEVERE AS IT WAS.
SO IF YOU WERE RUNNING THINGS
AT THAT SCHOOL, STEVE, WHAT DO
YOU DO WHEN IT FINALLY OPENS
UP PRESUMING IT DOES AGAIN?
>> BELIEVE YOUR EYES AND EARS
BUT WHEN YOU HEAR GUNSHOTS OR
IF YOU SEE -- I CAN'T
COMPREHEND HE WASN'T AT SOME
POINT OBSERVED BY SOMEONE
WALKING IN TO THAT SCHOOL.
>> YEAH.
>> CALLING AN ALARM.
BELIEVE EYES AND EARS.
IF YOU HEAR GUNSHOT RUN FROM
THE CARNAGE.
THE FATALITY DID OCCUR IN ONE
CLASSROOM.
DISTURBING AS THIS IS.
>> Jon: THAT I BELIEVE IS
RICHARD BLUMENTHAL, THE FORMER
ATTORNEY GENERAL IN
CONNECTICUT WHO ARRIVED AT THE
PODIUM.
THE OTHERS, I'M NOT FAMILIAR
WITH AT THIS POINT.
WE ARE ALSO EXPECTING THAT WE
WILL HEAR SOMETHING NEW FROM
POLICE ABOUT THIS INCREDIBLE
TRAGEDY.
ONCE AGAIN, 20 CHILDREN
MURDERED IN THEIR CLASSROOM.
SIX ADULTS AS WELL.
WE ARE GOING TO CONTINUEBE TO
BRING YOU