JENNA: HOW YOU CAN HELP,
FOXNEWS.COM.
WE HAVE RESOURCES FOR THOSE
THAT FEEL MOVE FOR THE
COMMUNITY.
CHECK OUT GREAT RESOURCES.
CONTINUE TO HAVE A GOOD
MONDAY AS WE WATCH FLAG AT
HALF-STAFF ACROSS THE NATION.
JON: MAKE BEGIN -- MEGYN
KELLY UP WITH AMERICA LIVE
MEGYN: WELCOME, EVERYBODY.
NEW INFORMATION FROM SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
WE LEARN MORE ABOUT THE
ADMINISTRATION'S PLANS.
BEGINNINGS OF PLANS, TRYING
TO PREVENT SIMILAR INCIDENTS
IN THE FUTURE.
WELCOME TO "AMERICA LIVE".
I'M MEGYN KELLY.
CONNECTICUT POLICE ARE
SAYING TWO UNIDENTIFIED
ADULTS WERE SHOT DURING THE
RAMPAGE ON FRIDAY.
THEY'RE NOW RECOVERING THAT
IS POTENTIALLY BENEFICIAL
OBVIOUSLY TO LAW ENFORCEMENT
AS WELL AS COMING AS A SIGH
OF RELIEF FOR THEIR
FAMILIES.
THE NEWS, COMING AS THE
COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN BEGINS
TO MOURN, THE 26 VICTIMS WHO
DID NOT SURVIVE ON FRIDAY T
WAS AN EMOTIONAL MEMORIAL
CEREMONY AT NEWTOWN HIGH
SCHOOL LAST NIGHT.
PRESIDENT OBAMA, SITTING
AMONG THE MOURNERS, IN THE
HIGH SCHOOL, JOINING
COMMUNITY AND RELIGIOUS
LEADERS AT THE SERVICE.
FIRST THOUGH HE MET
PRIVATELY WITH EACH OF THE
FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS.
WHAT, WHAT AN EXPERIENCE
THAT MUST HAVE BEEN.
AND YOU COULD SEE, THAT HE
WAS VISIBLY MOVED WHEN HE
CAME OUT OF ON THE STAGE AND
THE ENTIRE NATION HAS BEEN
MOVED BY THE EVENTS IN --
NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT, 72
HOURS AGO.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY WILL
REMAIN CLOSED INDEFINITELY,
PERHAPS A MONTH OR PERHAPS
PERMANENTLY AS THE
INVESTIGATION CONTINUES AND
AS THEY LEARN MORE ABOUT THE
GUNMAN, ADAM LANZA, WHAT MAY
HAVE MOTIVATED THIS TERRIBLE
UNSPEAKABLE CRIME.
RICK LEVENTHAL JOINS US LIVE
FROM NEWTOWN WITH THE LATEST
ON THAT INVESTIGATION.
RICK?
>> Reporter: MEGYN, YOU MAY
HAVE HEARD PAUL VANCE SAY
THERE WERE MOVING VANS,
COLLECTING FURNITURE OF THE
CLASSROOM OTHER EQUIPMENT
FROM THE SCHOOL SO IT CAN BE
MOVED TO ANOTHER SCHOOL,
CHALK HILL ELEMENTARY IN
MONROE, CONNECTICUT.
THAT IS WHERE THE SANDY HOOK
KIDS WHO SURVIVED THE
SHOOTING WILL ATTEND CLASSES
LATER THIS WEEK.
HE MENTIONED ABOUT ALL THE
BROKEN HEARTS IN THE
COMMUNITY AND HOW IMPORTANT
IT IS TO CONDUCT THE
INVESTIGATION THOROUGHLY AND
THIS IS LAST PRESS BRIEFING
THAT WE EXPECT TO GET FOR
SOME TIME AS THEY LOOK INTO
MOTIVES AND WHAT HAPPENED
HERE AND WHY.
POLICE TOLD US THEY'RE
HOLDING TWO CRIME SCENES
INDEFINITELY AND WHERE NANCY
LANZA LIVED AND WHERE SHE
DIED AFTER HE SHOT HER
MULTIPLE TIMES.
SANDY HOOK IS STILL A CRIME
SCENE THAT IS WHERE SIX
ADULTS AND 20 CHILDREN WERE
KILLED.
THEY RECOVERED SIGNIFICANT
EVIDENCE FROM THE HOME THAT
APPARENTLY INCLUDES ONE
COMPUTER AND TELEPHONES AND
OTHER ELECTRONIC EVIDENCE
THEY WILL BE SEARCHING
THROUGH.
THEY'RE INTERVIEWING EVERY
SINGLE WITNESS.
THAT WILL UNFORTUNATELY HAVE
TO INCLUDE THE CHILDREN FROM
THE SCHOOL WHO SURVIVED THE
SHOOTING.
I ASKED THE LIEUTENANT
EARLIER TODAY ABOUT HOW THEY
WOULD BALANCE THAT.
HERE IS WHAT HE TOLD US.
>> I DON'T WANT TO GET INTO
DETAILS OF A VERY, VERY,
TENDER, TENDER ISSUE.
I CAN TELL YOU THAT ANY
INTERVIEWS WITH ANY CHILDREN
WILL BE DONE WITH
PROFESSIONAL, WITH PARENTS
AND WITH INVESTIGATORS AS
APPROPRIATE.
THE INVESTIGATORS WILL
DETERMINE HOW, WHEN, WHERE
AND WHY WE'LL DO THIS.
AGAIN, WE'LL HANDLE THAT
EXTREMELY DELICATELY.
>> Reporter: THIS MORNING
FAMILY AND FRIENDS OF ADAM
LANZA ARE DESCRIBING HIM AS
NEAR GENIUS WHO HAD A FORM
OF AUTISM KNOWN AS ASPERGER'S.
HE MAY HAVE ATTENDED SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY AS A CHILD
BUT WAS LATER HOMESCHOOLED
AND TOOK COLLEGE COURSES AT
THE AGE OF 16 AT WESTERN
CONNECTICUT STATE
UNIVERSITY.
HE DIDN'T COMPLETE ALL OF
COURSES.
THE ONES HE DID ENDED UP
WITH A GPA OF 3.26.
WE LEARNED THE WEAPONS HE
USED IN THE SHOOTING ON
FRIDAY DID BELONG TO HIS THE
MOTHER.
WE HAVE AGAIN ALSO LEARNED
THAT THE STUDENTS WHO
ATTENDED THAT SCHOOL WILL,
AT SOME POINT LATER THIS
WEEK BE ATTENDING ANOTHER
SCHOOL AS THIS COMMUNITY,
MEGYN MOURNS ALL OF THOSE
WHO WERE LOST.
TWO FUNERALS TODAY AND MORE
FUNERALS EACH AND EVERY DAY
THIS WEEK.
MEGYN: RICK, WHEN WE WERE ON
THE AIR TOGETHER ON FRIDAY
AS THIS WAS UNFOLDING WE'RE
TOLD BY LAW ENFORCEMENT, THE
SHOOTER WAS RYAN LANZA, THE
ACTUAL SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA,
24-YEAR-OLD BROTHER.
THE INVESTIGATORS SPOKE WITH
HIM.
THEY SPOKE WITH THE FATHER
OF THESE TWO BOYS.
THE PARENTS WERE DIVORCED.
HAVE THEY BEEN ABLE TO OFFER
THE POLICE ANY ASSISTANCE
THAT IS MEANINGFUL AND HAVE
THEY NOW BEEN CLEARED OF
ANYTHING IN THIS
INVESTIGATION?
>> Reporter: MY
UNDERSTANDING IS THEY HAVE
BEEN CLEARED.
THEY WERE ALSO DESCRIBED AS
VERY COOPERATIVE.
THEY GAVE INVESTIGATORS
INSIGHT TO THE MINDSET OF AD
MANY TODAY LANZA.
MY UNDERSTANDING THEY WERE
ESTRANGED FOR SOME TIME.
AS YOU MAY KNOW, APPARENTLY
ADAM WAS CARRYING RYAN'S
IDENTIFICATION.
WHEN HE WAS FOUND IN THE
SCHOOL THAT'S WHY THEY
INITIALLY THOUGHT HE MIGHT
BE RYAN.
THAT IS WHAT SENT
INVESTIGATORS TO RYAN'S HOME
IN HOBOKEN WHERE THEY FOUND
ADAM'S BROTHER WHO EXPLAINED
THE SITUATION AND THAT
HELPED SORT OF UNSPOOL THIS
WHOLE INVESTIGATION.
MEGYN: THE REPORTS ARE ADAM
LANDS IS A HAD NO -- LANZA
HAD NO CRIMINAL HISTORY BUT
WAS OBVIOUSLY UNWELL.
HER MOTHER LED TO A
SHELTERED LIFE OF HER SON.
WHEN SHE WAS IN TOWN SHE
DIDN'T LIKE TO TALK ABOUT
HER SOME AD DOOM.
SHE PULLED HIM OUT OF FOR
HOMESCHOOLING.
THESE ARE ALL THE REPORTS
WE'RE GETTING.
ANY INSIGHT FROM THE THOSE
WHO KNEW THE BOY GROWING UP
AND WHAT HE WAS LIKE AND
WHETHER THERE WERE RED FLAGS
SO MANY MENTAL HEALTH
EXPERTS THERE ARE IN THESE
TYPES OF SITUATIONS?
>> Reporter: YOU KNOW WE'VE
BEEN TOLD THAT HE WAS SOCIAL
LE AWKWARD.
WE ALSO HEARD HE WAS RARELY
SEEN.
THAT HIS MOTHER KEPT HIM
SHELTERED INSIDE THE HOME
AND HE RARELY LEFT THAT
HOUSE.
NOT HEARING A LOT FROM
PEOPLE IN THE COMMUNITY
ABOUT HIM.
SORT OF A MYSTERY KID.
AGAIN, WAS ONLY APPARENTLY
AT THAT SCHOOL FOR A SHORT
TIME BEFORE HE WAS PULLED
OUT, SENT TO ANOTHER SCHOOL
AND HOMESCHOOLED.
THERE ARE REPORTS, MEGYN,
HIS MOTHER WAS PLANNING TO
MOVE, TO HELP HIS, HER SON
ATTEND A COLLEGE OUT WEST,
PERHAPS, IN WASHINGTON STATE.
BUT, OBVIOUSLY JUST A
TERRIBLE, TERRIBLE
SITUATION.
MEGYN: YEAH.
WE'LL HAVE MUCH MORE ON THE
INVESTIGATION THROUGHOUT THE
NEXT TWO HOURS BECAUSE WE
ARE LEARNING QUITE A BIT.
RICK, THANK YOU.
AS RICK JUST REPORTED WE ARE
LEARNING MORE ABOUT WHAT
KIND OF HOME LIFE ADAM LANZA
HAD AND THE KIND OF
STRUGGLES HIS FAMILY WAS
FACING.
BY ALL REPORTS THE GUNMAN'S
MOTHER, NANCY LANZA WAS THE
FIRST VICTIM.
FRIENDS SAY SHE WAS
EXTREMELY WORRIED ABOUT HER
SON PARTICULARLY IN THE LAST
COUPLE OF YEARS.
EARLIER TODAY FOX'S OWN
PETER DOOCY SPOKE TO A
FAMILY FRIEND ABOUT THE
RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN ADAM
AND HIS MOTHER.
>> Reporter: YOU SAID THERE
WERE DIFFERENT THINGS THAT
SHE TRIED TO DO BECAUSE SHE
HAD A HARD TIME BONDING WITH
HIM?
>> YEAH.
SHE WAS TRYING TO BOND, FIND
WAYS TO BOND WITH HIM AND
YOU KNOW, SHE TOLD ME THAT
THE GUNS, YOU KNOW, SHE
WOULD TAKE THEM SHOOTING
BECAUSE THAT WAS A WAY THAT,
YOU KNOW, A SINGLE MOM
COULD, YOU KNOW, RELATE TO
HER SON.
AND SO SHE WOULD TAKE HIM,
TAKE HIM OUT SHOOTING.
MEGYN: GIVEN WHAT WE'RE
LEARNING ABOUT ADAM AND HIS
APPARENT TROUBLES THE
QUESTION BECOMES, SHOULD
SOMEONE HAVE SEEN THIS
COMING?
DR. ALAN LIPMAN, CRIMINAL
PSYCHOLOGIST AND EXECUTIVE
DIRECTOR FOR THE STUDY OF
VIOLENCE IS WITH ME NOW.
DR. LIPMAN, WE'VE COME TO
RELY ON YOU A LOT IN THESE
TERRIBLE CIRCUMSTANCE AS
SOMEONE WHO CAN PROVIDE
INSIGHT TO THE CRIMINAL
MIND.
MANY FOLKS WANT TO BELIEVE
THIS IS A STORY ABOUT ANY
NUMBER OF THINGS, GUN
CONTROL, WHAT HAVE YOU, BUT
AT THE BEGINNING DON'T WE
HAVE TO START WITH WHAT MADE
THE SHOOTER WANT TO KILL?
>> WELL, LET'S THINK ABOUT
THIS AND IT IS TRUE AGAIN
YOU AND I JOIN IN A TRAGIC
SITUATION AND OUR HEARTS OF
COURSE GO OUT TO THOSE
FAMILIES IN CONNECTICUT.
EVERYONE OF US ACROSS THE
NATION.
BUT, LOOK, THE FACT IS, THAT
AS WE'VE SEEN, WE SAW IN
AURORA, COLORADO, WITH
HOLMES, WE SAW IN VIRGINIA
TECH WITH CHO AND WE SAW
WITH LOUGHNER IN TUCSON,
ARIZONA, IN EVERY SINGLE ONE
OF THESE CASES AND U.S.
SECRET SERVICE STUDY LOOKED
AT OVER 20 YEARS OF THESE
EPISODES, BEFORE VIRTUALLY
EVERY SINGLE ONE THERE WAS
UNDIAGNOSED OR
INSUFFICIENTLY TREATED
MENTAL ILLNESS.
AGAIN WE SEE AT THE PRIME
AGE, LATE TEENS OR EARLY 20s,
WHEN A PERSON ERUPTS INTO
PSYCHOSIS, THIS IS WHAT
WE'RE SEEING AGAIN WITH ADAM
LANZA.
YOU JUST REPORTED, ONE OF
YOUR REPORTERS WAS NOTING
THAT NANCY LANZA WAS HAVING
INCREASING TROUBLE WITH ADAM
OVER THESE LAST COUPLE
YEARS.
THIS IS HOW IT WORKS.
THE PERSON FIRST SHOWS A
PATTERN OF ABNORMAL SOCIAL
BEHAVIOR.
THAT IS A KEY SIGN OF THE,
PRECEDING SIGNS OF
SCHIZOPHRENIA.
THEY BECOME MORE AND MORE
DIFFICULT.
IN LATE TEENS OR EARLY 20s
THEY BREAK INTO SIGH COAST
KISS.
QUITE LIKELY ALTHOUGH WE
DON'T KNOW FOR CERTAIN, THAT
IS THE CASE AS IN ALL OF
THESE OTHER SHOOTINGS THAT
WE'VE SEEN HAPPENED HERE --
PSYCHOSIS.
MEGYN: RIGHT.
>> MEGYN, IT IS THE CASE IF
YOU HAVE SOMEONE AS WITH
HOLMES, AS WITH LOUGHNER AND
APPEARS TO BE THE CASE WITH
LANZA, CHO, ALL THE WAY BACK
TO COLUMBINE, IF YOU HAVE
SOMEONE FILLED WITH RAGE,
FILLED WITH DELUSIONS,
FILLED WITH VENGANCE AND
THEY CAN SIMPLY LAY THEIR
HANDS ON SOMETHING THAT WILL
ALLOW THAT VENGANCE TO BE
QUICKLY ACTED UPON RATHER
THAN DELAYED, THAT IS A VERY
POWERFUL COMBINATION.
WE, NEED TO BEGIN A NATIONAL
DIALOGUE IN WHICH WE TEACH
PEOPLE HOW TO IDENTIFY THE
SIGNS OF MENTAL ILLNESS THAT
WE HAVE BEEN SO AFRAID TO
LOOK AT.
YOU KNOW, IN EVERYONE OF
THESE INCIDENTS BEFOREHAND I
HEARD OVER THE YEARS SINCE
EARLY DAYS AT YALE, HOW CAN
THIS HAPPEN?
I CAN'T BELIEVE THIS HAS
HAPPENED?
HOW CAN WE EXPLAIN IT?
WE KNOW WHY.
WHAT WE NEED TO BE ABLE TO
DO IS TO TEACH PEOPLE,
PARENTS, EDUCATORS, CITIZENS,
HOW TO IDENTIFY THE SIGNS
MENTAL ILLNESS IN THEIR
CHILDREN, AND MEGYN, HOW TO
INTERVENE.
MEGYN, THIS IS SOMETHING WE
CAN TEACH AND WE CAN DO.
MEGYN: THIS IS THE QUESTION
I HAVE FOR YOU.
QUITE FRANKLY, I'M SURE YOU
FEEL THE SAME, I'M SICK OF
YOU HAVING THE CONVERSATION.
>> ME TOO.
ENOUGH OF IT FOR GOD'S
SAKES.
MEGYN: YOU SAID BEFORE LONG
BEFORE WE KNEW THE NAME ADAM
LANZA,, LATE TEENS, EARLY
20S YOU HAVE THE FIRST
PSYCHOTIC BREAK.
WE'VE SEEN IT MANY TIMES.
WE DON'T KNOW THAT'S WHAT
HAPPENED HERE BUT CLEARLY --
>> YOU WANT TO KNOW WHAT THE
PROBLEM IS?
MEGYN: THE WHOLE COUNTRY
WANTS TO KNOW.
>> WHY WE HAVE THIS
CONVERSATION AGAIN AND
AGAIN?
HERE IS WHAT I BELIEVE.
I'VE BEEN LOOKING AT NOW FOR
OVER 20 YEARS.
THERE ARE TWO REASONS, OKAY?
THE FIRST, WE AS A NATION
NEED TO UNDERSTAND THAT
MENTAL ILLNESS SHOULD NOT BE
STIGMATIZED AND IT IS NOT AN
EXCUSE.
THESE PEOPLE ARE RESPONSIBLE
FOR THEIR ACTIONS.
BUT IF WE DON'T LOOK AT THAT
CAUSE, IF WE DON'T LEARN TO
SEE IT, UNDERSTAND IT, SEE
THE SIGNS, AND LEARN HOW TO
INTERVENE, AS PARENTS,
EDUCATORS, FRIENDS, CITIZENS
OF THIS NATION, WE WILL SEE
THIS CYCLE REPEAT AGAIN AND
AGAIN.
WE NEED TO LOOK AT IT, TO
GET OVER OUR OWN DISCOMFORT.
TO IDENTIFY THE SIGNS, AND
TO BE ABLE TO LEARN TO
INTERVENE.
AND SECONDLY, IF WE KNOW
THAT WE HAVE A CHILD WHO IS
VIOLENT, WHO IS OUT OF
CONTROL, WHO IS IN FACT
SUFFERING FROM THESE KINDS
OF SYMPTOMS, WE NEED TO TAKE
THEM TO A HOSPITAL, TO A:I
CAN TO A DOCTOR LIKE MYSELF
AND NOT LEAVE THEM IN THE
PRESENCE OF SOMETHING.
MEGYN: I HAVE 50 SECONDS.
60 SECONDS BEFORE HARD
BREAK.
BUT I HAVE TO GET THIS IN.
IS THERE A PLACE FOR THEM IN
THE SYSTEM?
DO WE COMMIT THEM?
IS IT JUST THE --
>> IS THERE A PLACE?
MEGYN: PLACE FOR PEOPLE WHO
HAVEN'T COMMITTED A CRIME
BUT DON'T NECESSARILY
WARRANT COMMITMENT?
>> MEGYN, HEAR IS THE PLACE.
THE PLACE IS IN OUR OWN
MINDS.
AS MEMBERS OF THIS COMMUNITY
TO IDENTIFY THE SIGNS SO
THAT WE CAN TAKE THEM TO THE
PLACES WHERE WE CAN GIVE
THEM THE TREATMENT THAT WE
ALREADY HAVE.
THERE IS NOT A LACK OF
AVAILABLE TREATMENTS.
THERE IS LACK OF AVAILABLE
SIGHT.
AND WE NEED TO, AS A NATION,
MAKE IT A NATIONAL PRIORITY
TO IDENTIFY THE SIGNS OF
MENTAL ILLNESS BEFORE
HAPPENED SO THAT WE CAN
PREVENT THESE TRAGEDIES,
PREVENT THIS HORRIFIC GRIEF
IN OUR NATION.
WE KNOW THE REASONS.
WE NEED TO OPEN OUR EYES,
LEARN THE SIGNS, AND TAKE
THE ACTIONS TO INTERVENE.
MEGYN: DR. LIPMAN, WE'LL SEE
MORE OF YOU IN THE COMING
DAYS BECAUSE WE NEED TO
DELVE DEEPER.
>> I AGREE.
MEGYN: LOOK FOR SIGNS TO
WATCH OUT FOR.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US.
>> ALL THE BEST.
MEGYN: UP NEXT, ONE OF THE
FIRST SCHOOL SECURITY
EXPERTS TO SPEAK TO THE
RESIDENTS OF COLUMBINE WILL
JOIN US LIVE ON THE NEWTOWN
SHOOTINGS.
STAY WITH ME.
>> SOMETHING THAT YOU NEVER
REALLY SEE, YOU KNOW, ALL
THE JOINT FAITHS COMING
TOGETHER AND SHARING AS ONE.
I THOUGHT IT WAS REMARKABLE.
IN A TIME OF CRISIS LIKE
THIS, WE ARE ONE.
WE ARE ONE NATION.
♪ THE WEATHER OUTSIDE
IS FRIGHTFUL ♪
♪ BUT THE FIRE IS
SO DELIGHTFUL ♪
NOTHING MELTS AWAY THE COLD
LIKE A HOT, DELICIOUS BOWL
OF CHICKEN NOODLE SOUP
FROM CAMPBELL'S.
♪ LET IT SNOW, LET IT SNOW
HI,
I'M Ensure Clear...
Clear, HUH?
I'M NOT JUICE OR FANCY WATER.
I'VE GOTINE GRAMS OF PROTEIN.
THAT'S THREE TIMES MORE THAN ME!
[ Female Announcer ]
Ensure Clear.
NINE GRAMS PROTEIN. ZERO FAT.
THE RED CROSS WAS DOWN HERE
ALL THE TIME.
[ man ]
THEY'VE GIVEN US A LOT OF HEART.
IN TIMES OF NEED, THEY'RE THERE.
♪
[ Kerry ] MY DAD WAS WATCHING
HIS HOUSE BURN.
HE TURNED AROUND,
AND ALL OF A SUDDEN, THERWAS
THIS GUY STANDING THERE
FROM THE RED CROSS.
AT A POINT WHERE I HAD
JUST LOST EVERYTHING,
THE IDEA THAT THERE WAS
SOMEONE THERE...
THAT'S AN AMAZING THING.
♪
YEAH. AND YOU CAN GET IT
WITH VIRGIN MOBILE'S PLAN.
$35 A MONTH
WITH UNLIMITED DATA
D MESSAGING INCLUDED.
WITH ALL THE WEB SURFING
I WANT?
YEP.
SOUNDS LIKE A DATA BUFFET.
AN ALL-YOU-CAN-EAT
DATAUFFET.
U KNOW WHO WOULD LOVE
UR ALL-YOU-CAN-EAT-DATA BUFFET?
BIG LUCY.
BIG LUCY!
ARE YOU HUNGRY?
FOR ALL THE DATA.
[ Male Announcer ] GET THE
SEASON'S HOTTEST SMARTPHONES,
LIKE THE KYOCERA RISE.
AND GET VIRGIN MOBILE,
WITH UNLIMITED DATA AND
MESSAGING INCLUDED,
FOR JUST $35 A MONTH.
FROM AMERICA'S
GIFT HEADQUARTERS. WALMART.
MEGYN: THE WHITE HOUSE PRESS
BRIEFING IS EXPECTED TO BEGIN
ANY MORNING WHERE WE'LL LEARN
THE ADMINISTRATIONS PLAN TO COME
UP WITH WAYS TO PREVENT WHAT
HAPPENED IN NEWTOWN.
YOU CAN SEE JAY CARNEY TAKING TO
THE MICROPHONES THERE.
WE WILL MONITOR IT FOR YOU AS
THEY GET TO NEWS ON NEWTOWN
WE'LL BRING IT TO YOU.
ACROSS THE COUNTRY YOU SAW SIGNS
OF INCREASED SECURITY AT SCHOOLS
IN THE WAKE OF THIS TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT.
FOR INSTANCE, POLICE RECRUITS IN
MILLION WALKEE UNDERGOING
TRAINING OVER THE WEEKEND TO
DEAL WITH TRAGIC SITUATIONS,
SIMILAR TO FRIDAY APARTMENT
RAMPAGE.
AS KIDS SHOWED UP TO SCHOOL
POSSIBLY KEYING ARMED POLICE
OFFICERS IN FRONT OF THEIR
SCHOOL.
HOW FAR SHOULD WE GO TO KEEP OUR
KIDS SAFE?
DR. JAMES SHAW IS A SCHOOL
SECURITY, SAFETY AND VIOLENCE
EXPERT, A TRUE EXPERT AT THE
CHICAGO SCHOOL OF PSYCHOLOGY AND
AUTHOR OF THE BOOK "JACK AND
JILL, WHY THEY KILL" YOU SPOKE
AT THE COMMENCEMENT CEREMONY AT
COLUMBINE HIGH SCHOOL SHORTLY
AFTER THE MASSACRE THERE AND YOU
KNOW WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT
WHEN IT COMES TO THIS ADOLESCENT
SIDE, I MEAN YOUNG, YOUNG PEOPLE
IN THIS COUNTRY, WHETHER IT'S
LATE TEENS OR EARLY 20S,
COMMITTING MASS MURDER.
BACK THEN THIS IS YOU APRIL 20,
2000 SAYING, WE MUST REQUIRE OF
OURSELVES THAT WE DO MORE THAN
GRIEVE.
WHAT KIND OF INSPIRATION,
MOTIVATION OR DIRECTION DO WE
MEAD TO MAKE US PROTECT OUR
CHILDREN AGAINST VIOLENCE,
INCLUDING IN SCHOOL?
APPARENTLY WE NEEDED A LITTLE
MORE.
>> I AGREE, MEGYN.
DR. LIPMAN SAID A LOT OF
TRUTHFUL THINGS IN HIS
STATEMENT.
ONE OF THE THINGS HE SAID IS TO
LOOK FOR THE SIGNS.
I WOULD LIKE TO ADD TO THAT.
LOOK FOR THE SIGNS OF SOMEONE
WHO IS GETTING READY TO ENGAGE
IN NEGATIVE BEHAVIOR.
FOR EXAMPLE, MORE AND MORE PRESS
STORIES ARE SAYING THAT THE
SLAIN SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA HAD A
VERBAL CONFLICT WITH SCHOOL
STAFF THE DAY BEFORE THE
SHOOTING, LESS THAN 24 HOURS
BEFORE HE WENT OFF, SO TO
SPEAK.
WE NOW SADLY KNOW AFTER THE FACT
THAT WE CAN USE VERBAL DISPUTES
AS SCHOOL PEOPLE, VERBAL
CONTACTS, THREATS, AS A REPB T
AS A REASON TO DENY ENTRY.
IF YOU HAVE A VERBAL DISPUTE
WITH SOMEONE YOU DON'T LET THEM
THROUGH INTO THE SCHOOL.
AIRLINES HAVE DONE THAT, IF
SOMEONE IS ACTING VERBALLY OR
MAKING THREATS, HE OR SHE CANNOT
GET ON THE PLANE.
MEGYN: WE KNOW HE SHOT HIS WAY
IN THE NEXT DAY MAYBE YOU ARE ON
A HIGHER ALERT WHEN AN
ALTERCATION HAS TAKEN PLACE.
MAYBI DEFINITELY WANT TO SPEAK
WITH YOU.
JAY CARNEY HAS JUST BEEN ASKED
ABOUT GUN CONTROL AND WHETHER
THAT WILL BE A NEW PUSH BY THE
PRESIDENT.
>> I THINK THAT IT'S PART OF IT,
BUT IT IS FAR FROM AWFU FROM
ALL OF IT.
AS YOU KNOW THE PRESIDENT HAS
TAKEN POSITIONS ON COMMON-SENSE
MEASURES THAT HE BELIEVES SHOULD
BE TAKEN TO HELP ADDRESS THIS
PROBLEM, BUT HE MADE CLEAR THAT
MORE NEEDS TO BE DONE, THAT WE
AS A NATION HAVE NOT DONE ENOUGH
CLEARLY TO FULFILL OUR NUMBER
ONE OBLIGATION, WHICH IS TO
PROTECT OUR CHILDREN.
>> ONE MORE ON THIS.
AS YOU KNOW WE'VE SEEN THESE
HORRIFIC MOMENTS COME AND GO,
AND THE DEBATE GOOD GUN SAFETY,
CHILDREN SAFETY GOES WITNESS.
DOES THE PRESIDENT THINK THAT HE
NEEDS TO CAPITALIZE ON THIS AND
GET THIS CONVERSATION GOING AND
SEE SOME ACTION IN THE SHORT
TERM, OR DOES HE FEEL LIKE HE
CAN GET THROUGH FISCAL CLIFF,
IMMIGRATION AND THERE IS NOW A
MINDSET AND A WILL TO GET THIS
DONE MONTHS DOWN THE LINE?
>> I DON'T HAVE A SPECIFIC
TIMELINE FOR YOU FOR WHAT THE
PRESIDENT WILL DO MOVING
FORWARD.
I WOULD SIMPLY REFER YOU TO HIS
REMARKS LAST NIGHT WHEN HE
TALKED ABOUT THE ACTION HE HOPED
TO TAKE TO ENGAGE THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE IN THE COMING WEEKS.
I THINK THAT WHAT HAPPENED AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HAS
CLEARLY SHOCKED THE ENTIRE
NATION, AND HAS LAID BARE THE
NECESSITY OF EVALUATING THE
VARIOUS THINGS THAT WE CAN AND
MUST DO AS A NATION TO TRY TO
BETTER PROTECT OUR CHILDREN.
>> QUICKLY ON FISCAL CLIFF, THE
PRESIDENT SAID TO THE BUSINESS
ROUNDTABLE RECENTLY THAT
REPUBLICANS NEED TO REACH WHAT
HE CALLED A CONCEPTUAL
BREAKTHROUGH ON RATES, TAX RATES
GOING UP AND ONCE THAT HAPPENS
THE DEAL WILL COME TOGETHER
PRETTY QUICKLY.
DOES HE FEEL HE HAS THAT NOW
THAT SPEAKER BOEHNER IS TALKING
ABOUT RATES, AS FAR AS IN
CONVERSATION?
>> I WON'T COMMENT ON SPECIFIC
REPORTED PROPOSALS OR COUNTER
PROPOSALS ON INTERNAL
CONVERSATIONS BETWEEN THE
PRESIDENT AND THE SPEAKER, OR
THE PRESIDENT'S TEAM AND THE
SPEAKERS TEAM, OR WITH OTHER
MEMBERS OF LEADERSHIP.
THE PRESIDENT'S INSISTENCE THAT
RATES NEED TO GO UP ON THE TOP
2% WAS BASED ON AN ECONOMIC
REALITY, WHICH IS THAT IN ORDER
TO ACHIEVE A BROAD DEFICIT
REDUCTION IMAGINE THAT PUTS OUR
ECONOMY --
MEGYN: HR-RBGTS YO YOU HEARD
JAY CARNEY ECHOING WHAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID LAST
NIGHT.
THE PRESIDENT IN ELLA KWEPBT
REMARKS IN NEWTOWN TALKED ABOUT
HOW WE ARE FAILING OUR CHILDREN
IN THIS NATION, WE ARE FAILING
THEM WHEN IT COMES TO THEIR
SAFETY.
AND THAT HE'S BEEN TO TOO MANY
OF THESE MEMORIAL SERVICES WHERE
INNOCENT VICTIMS ARE BEING
KILLED, AND HE DIDN'T SPEAK
ABOUT GUN CONTROL, HE JUST
TALKED ABOUT HOW HE NEEDED TO
SIT WITH ADVISERS, WITH EXPERTS
AND COME UP WITH WAYS THAT WE
CAN IMPROVE THE SITUATION.
MANY BELIEVED HE WAS TALKING
MAYBE AT LEAST IN PART ABOUT AN
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN WHICH HAS
BEEN VERY MUCH IN THE NEWS
LATELY BUT THE WHITE HOUSE NOT
CONFIRMING THAT RIGHT THERE.
A CONVERSATION IS GOING TO BEGIN
IN THIS COUNTRY AND HOPEFULLY
ABOUT MANY ISSUES, INCLUDING AS
WE TALKED ABOUT MOMENTS AGO,
WHAT WOULD MAKE SWAN WANT TO
KILL IN THISOMEONE WANT TO KILL
IN THIS WAY IN THE FIRST PLACE.
WE HAD DR. JAMES SHAW, HIS
SATELLITE FEED WENT DOWN.
WE WILL GET HIM BACK UP.
I REALLY DO WANT YOU TO HEAR
FROM HIM.
IT'S SO HARD TO FIND PEOPLE WHO
ARE TRULY EXPERTS IN THIS KIND
OF THING, IN SCHOOL SECURITY AND
HE'S ONE OF THEM.
WE GOT HIM?
LET'S BRING BACK DR. SHAW.
WELCOME BACK.
IN TERMS OF RECOGNIZING THE
SIGNS, YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN,
MOST PEOPLE ARE REGULAR FOLKS,
THEY SEE SOMEBODY, HE'S WEIRD,
HE'S ODD, HE'S SHY, HE KEEPS TO
HIMSELF.
THIS GUY THEY SAID HE DRESSED
MORE FORMALLY, HE HELD A
BRIEFCASE IN HIGH SCHOOL.
HE WOULD PUSH UP AGAIN THE
LOCKERS WHEN FRIENDS WENT BY, HE
DIDN'T LIKE TO TALK TO ANYBODY.
HOW DO YOU DISCERN THAT FROM SHY
NECESSARY, AWKWARDNESS,
ASBURGERS WHICH CAN BE A SOCIAL
IMPEDIMENT FOR SOME FOLKS FROM A
WOULD BE MURDERER.
>> I WOULD ADVISE EVERYBODY NOT
TO START LABELING, NOT USE TERMS
LIKE ASBURGERS OR AUTISM.
I THINK THAT IS INCORRECT, IT'S
WRONG, IT'S OFFENSIVE, IT'S LIKE
LABELING SOMEONE WHO IS TOO
SHORT OR TOO TALL OR
LEFT-HANDED, THAT KIND OF
THING.
I THINK IN THE IMMEDIATE NEWT WE
NEED TO START PAYING ATTENTION
TO POTENTIAL COPY-CATS.
AFTER COLUMBINE THERE WERE A
SPAYED OF COPY-CAT-TYPE EVENTS
ON HIGH SCHOOL CAMPUSES AROUND
THE COUNTRY.
I HOPE IT DOESN'T HAPPEN HERE,
BUT I THINK WE NEED TO KEEP OUR
RADAR UP AND ON, IN THE EVENT,
IN THE PROSPECT THAT THERE IS A
COPY-CAT OUT THERE WANTING TO
GET SOME KIND OF PRESTIGE,
WANTING TO GET SOME KIND OF
FLATTERY AND ATTENTION.
MEGYN: WE SAW IT AFTER
COLUMBINE.
DR. ABLOW WAS ON THE PROGRAM ON
FRIDAY TALKING ABOUT ONE OF THE
REASONS THIS IS VERY DISTURBING
WHAT HAPPENED IN NEWTOWN, WE
STILL BELIEVED IN THE WAKE OF
COLUMBINE AND OTHER INCIDENTS
THAT THERE WERE CERTAIN RED
LINES, EVEN THE MENTALLY
DERANGED, EVEN TERRORISTS WON'T
CROSS AND THE MASS MURDER OF SIX
AND SEVEN YEAR OLDS WAS ONE OF
THEM, WE JUST STILL BELIEVED
THAT.
THE FEAR IS THAT NOW THAT ONE
PERSON HAS CROSSED THAT RED
LINE, WHETHER IT'S ELIMINATED,
WHETHER THE RED LINE IS GONE.
DR. SHAW, AS SOMEBODY WHO DOES
THIS FOR A LIVING, WHAT DO YOU
SAY TO THE SCHOOL SYSTEMS OUT
THERE WHO NOW HAVE TO WORRY
ABOUT COPY-CATS AND THE PARENTS
OUT THERE WHO ARE VERY
CONCERNED?
>> I THINK SCHOOL DISTRICT, AND
SCHOOL SUPERINTENDENTS, AND
BOARDS OF EDUCATION, AND SCHOOL
PRINCIPALS NEED TO WORKDAY LEE,
IF NECESSARY, WITH LAW
ENFORCEMENT TO COME UP WITH
COGENT, STRATEGIC SCHOOL SAFETY
PLANS THAT MAKE SENSE, THAT ARE
EXECUTABLE AND THAT ARE
CURRENT.
I THINK SCHOOLS NEED CAMERAS,
HIGH-TECH, HIGH CAPACITY CAMERAS
IN THEIR FRONT OFFICES AND
OUTSIDE THE FRONT OFFICES,
AROUND PASSAGEWAYS AND
HALLWAYS.
I THINK SCHOOLS NEED TO HAVE
VISITOR SIGN ENTRY LOGS AND EXIT
LOGS.
JUST BECAUSE YOU KNOW A PERSON,
BECAUSE HE OR SHE IS REPEATEDLY
AT YOUR DESK IN THE FRONT HOFS
DOES NOT MEAN YOU LET YOUR GUARD
DOWN, DOES NOT MEAN YOU LET THEM
THROUGH THE ELECTRONIC GAME.
I AM CHEERED AND ENCOURAGED BY
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S WANTING TO
HELP EVERY SCHOOL DISTRICT IN
THE NATION.
I THINK IT WOULD BE GOOD FOR HIM
TO LOOK AT THE FORMER DRUG
AND -- SAFE AND DRUG FREE
SCHOOLS ACT WHICH HAD BILLIONS
OF DOLLARS IN PAST
ADMINISTRATIONS OR TWO.
HOWEVER THEY WERE FUNDING THINGS
SUCH AS MAGIC SHOWS, AND DUNKING
TANKS AT SCHOOLS.
WE CAN DO MUCH BETTER THAN
THAT.
MEGYN: YOU KNOW, AND I -- WE'LL
TALK A LOT MORE ABOUT AUTISM AND
ASBURGERS.
THAT REPORTEDLY COMES FROM ADAM
LANZA'S BROTHER TO THE POLICE
SAYING THAT HE WAS ON THE AUTISM
SPECTRUM, AND WE WILL TALK A LOT
MORE ABOUT WAVING THAT MEANS.
I MEAN, YOU KNOW HOW MANY PEOPLE
IN THAT COUNTRY HAVE A DIAGNOSIS
OF SOME PLACE ON THE AUTISM
SPECTRUM, AND THE VAST MAJORITY
HAVE NO VIOLENT TENDENCIES, AND
THAT'S AN ASIDE ACCORDING TO
MOST OF THE EXPERTS BUT HAS
BECOME THE FOCUS OF SO MANY.
WE WILL TALK ABOUT WHETHER THAT
IS FAIR AND WHAT PEOPLE REALLY
NEED TO LOOK THE HERE.
I KNOW IT'S ONLY BEEN 72 HOURS.
THIS GUY THE POLICE SAY HE SHOT
HIS WAY IN.
THEY HAD THE CAMERAS AND THE
LOCKDOWN, THE TEACHERS DID
EVERYTHING RIGHT FROM THE SOUND
OF IT.
HOW COULD THEY HAVE DONE
SOMETHING DIFFERENTLY ON FRIDAY?
>> I DON'T KNOW, MEGYN THAT THEY
COULD HAVE.
I THINK THE TEACHERS, GOD REST
THEM, I THINK THE TEACHERS DID
EVERYTHING THEY POSSIBLY COULD.
THEY GAVE THEIR LIVES.
THEY RAN TOWARD THE SHOOTER, THE
PRINCIPAL, AND A TEACHER,
ANOTHER TEACHER OR TWO RAN
TOWARD THE SHOOTER TO BLOCK AND
PROTECT -- BLOCK AND PROTECT
KIDS BEHIND THEM AND AROUND
THEM.
WHEN YOU'VE DONE ALL THAT YOU
CAN DO, WHAT WAS IT THAT YOU
FAILED TO DO?
I DON'T KNOW.
I THINK THAT IS AN ETERNAL
QUESTION THAT WE ARE GOING TO BE
DEBATING, PONDERING AND TALKING
ABOUT FOR YEARS TO COME.
MEGYN: WHEN YOU FINISHED THOSE
REMARKS AT THE COLUMBINE
GRADUATION AFTER THE MASSACRE
YOU SAID MAY GOD SAVE THE
CHILDREN, MAY THE NATION'S
VICTIM.
DR. SHAW, THANK YOU FOR BEING
HERE WITH US.
>> THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
MEGYN: ALL THE BEST, SIR.
WE HAVE OTHER STORIES DEVELOPING
THIS HOUR, INCLUDING THERE IS
NEW FALLOUT ON THE TERROR ATTACK
ON OUR CONSULATE IN BENGE, LIBYA
ON 9/11 OF THIS YEAR AFTER
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON ANNOUNCES THAT SHE WILL
NOT BE ABLE TO TESTIFY TO
CONGRESS THIS THURSDAY, BECAUSE
OF A CONCUSSION SHE SUFFERED
SOME TIME LAST WEEK.
FOX NEWS CONTRIBUTOR MONICA
CROWLEY IS WITH US LIVE RIGHT
AFTER THE BREAK ON THAT.
WE'LL GET SOME OTHER NEWS IN
TODAY.
AFTER LAST WEEK'S PROUNION
PROTESTS IN MICHIGAN, ONE UNION
LEADER ISSUES A CONTROVERSIAL
CHALLENGE TO THE MICHIGAN
GOVERNOR THAT IS MAKING QUITE A
FEW HEADLINES TODAY.
PLUS, AS WE LEARN MORE ABOUT THE
HORRIFIC MASSACRE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT AND WE SEE THE FACES
OF SOME OF THE VICTIMS, HERE YOU
SEE THE ADULTS.
NEW STORIES OF HEROISM ARE
EMERGING.
TRACE GALLAGHER NEXT WITH SOME
POWERFUL STORIES ABOUT COURAGE
UNDER FIRE AND THE PEOPLE WHO
DID EVERYTHING THEY COULD TO
SAVE AS MANY LIV LIVES AS
POSSIBLE.
>> WE UNDERSTAND THE POWER OF
PRAYER IS WHAT IT IS AND WE KNOW
WE CAN INTERCEDE FOR PEOPLE.
WE DON'T HAVE TO BE HERE WE CAN
BE RIGHT HERE AND MAKE AN
IMPACT.
PEOPLE SAY EMAIL TRAVELS FAST,
BUT PRAYER TRAVELS FASTER.
[ Male Announcer ]
AT SCOTTRADE,
YOU WON'T JUST
FIND US ONLINE,
YOU'LL ALSO FIND US IN PERSON,
WITH DEDICATED SUPPORT TEAMS
AT OVER 500 BRANCHES
NATIONWIDE.
SO WHEN YOU CALL OR VISIT,
YOU CAN ASK FOR A NAME
YOU KNOW.
BECAUSE PERSONAL SERVICE
STARTS WITH A REAL PERSON.
[ Rodger ]
AT SCOTTRADE,
SEVEN DOLLAR TRADES
ARE JUST THE START.
OUR SUPPORT TEAMS
ARE NEARBY,
READY TO HELP.
IT'S NO WONDER SO MANY INVESTORS
ARE SAYING...
[ All ]
I'M WITH SCOTTRADE.
MEGYN: AS THE NATION MOURNS
THOSE KILLED IN THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL TRAGEDY WE ARE LEARNING
NEW INSPIRING STORIES OF THE
HEROS.
THE PRESENCE OF MIND THAT THOSE
INSIDE AND OUTSIDE OF THE
CLASSROOMS SHOWED ON FRIDAY, THE
SELFLESSNESS, THE COURAGE,
REMINDS US HOPEFULLY OF THE TRUE
NATURE OF HUMAN BEINGS ON THIS
EARTH.
TRACE GALLAGHER LIVE FROM OUR
LOS ANGELES BUREAU WITH SOME OF
THE STORIES.
TRACE.
>> YOU MAKE A VERY IMPORTANT
POINT, MEGYN, AS THE NATION IN
NEWTOWN GRIEVE FOR THE VICTIMS
THERE ARE ALSO PEOPLE WHO ARE
OFFERING PRAISE AND PRAYERS FOR
THE HEROS, AND THE HEROS ARE
MANY, PEOPLE WHO IN JUST A FEW
SPLIT SECONDS HAD THESE
INCREDIBLE ACTS OF VALOR LIKE
THE FIRST GRADE TEACHER
27-YEAR-OLD VICTORIA SOTO.
SHE TRIED AS FAST AS SHE COULD
TO GET HER CHILDREN INTO A
BATHROOM AND A CLOSET.
AND WHEN THE GUNMAN BROKE INTO
THE SCHOOL THE CHILDREN WHO WERE
NOT HIDDEN SHE TRIED TO SHIELD
WITH HER BODY.
LISTEN.
>> IT BRINGS PEACE TO THE FAMILY
TO KNOW SHE WAS PROTECTING THOSE
KIDS REGARD LEAFS THE INTIMATE
DETAILS THAT TOOK PLACE IN THAT
CLASSROOM WITH THE MONSTER THAT
CAME IN, HER INSTINCTS WERE TO
GET THOSE KIDS OUT OF HARM'S WAY
AND THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT SHE DID,
UNFORTUNATELY SHE LOST HER LIFE
DOING THAT.
>> HER FAMILY WENT ONTO SAY SHE
DID NOT CALL THEM HER STUDENTS,
SHE CALLED THEM HER KIDS AND SHE
CLEARLY MEANT IT.
THERE IS 52-YEAR-OLD ANNMARIE
MURPHY A SPECIAL EDUCATION
TEACHER WHO ALSO DIED USING HER
BODY TO BLOCK BULLETS AIMED AT
HER STUDENTS.
SHE WAS FOUND COVERING A CHILD
WHO DIED.
LISTEN.
>> SHE IS A HERO.
AND THAT GIVES US SOMETHING TO
HOLD ONTO.
I THINK THAT'S WHAT I'M HOLDING
ONTO RIGHT NOW IS THAT SHE IS A
HERO.
>> ANNMARIE MURPHY WAS A WIFE
AND MOTHER OF FOUR.
WHEN MUSIC TEACHER ROSA
KRISTOPECK HEARD GUNFIRE SHE
LOCKED ALL OF HER STUDENTS IN HA
STORAGE CLOSET.
MUSICAL INSTRUMENTS BLOCKED ONE
DOOR AND SHE HELD HER HAND
TIGHTLY TO THE KNOB ON THE OTHER
DOOR AND SHE HEARD THE SHOOTER
YELL, LET ME IN, LET ME IN.
SHE HELD ON, HER AND HER KIDS
SURVIVED.
THE ASSISTANT LIBRARIAN HAD 18
FOURTH GRADERS IN THE LIBRARY.
SHE HEARD THE COMMOTION OVER THE
INTERCOM.
SHE RUSHED ALL OF HER KIDS TO AN
EMPTY CLASSROOM, THEY BARRICADED
THE DOOR, THEY WAIT, THEY WAIT
AND THEY SURVIVED.
POLICE FINALLY PULLED THEM OUT.
JUST A FEW STORIES, MEGYN, MANY,
MANY HEROES ON THAT DAY,
REMEMBER SOME 650 TEACHERS AND
STUDENTS GOT OUT OF THAT SCHOOL
ALIVE, AND FOR EACH OF THEM
THERE IS A REASON.
MEGYN: INCREDIBLE.
THAT PRINCIPAL AND THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST SAID BY THE
AUTHORITIES TO HAVE RUSHED
TOWARD THE GUNMAN, SOMEONE
HAVING THE PEACE OF MIND TO
PRESS THE INTERCOM SYSTEM SO THE
KIDS WOULD HEAR, THE TEACHERS
WOULD HEAR THAT THERE WAS CHAOS
AND DANGER AND ONE FATHER I HAVE
TO MENTION THIS TELLING THE "NEW
YORK POST," HIS NAME IS NEAL
HEFLIN, HIS NAME JESSE LOUIS.
I WAS IN VICTORIA SOTO'S
CLASSROOM.
SHE GOT MOST OF THE KIDS INTO
THE BACK ROOM.
SEVEN OF THEM WERE BACK THERE
AND SIX OF THEM TRIED TO MAKE A
RUN FOR IT ANYWAY, AND JESSE,
HIS SON WAS ONE OF THEM.
HE WAS KILLED, AND MR. HEFLIN
SAID I WISH MY KID STAYED PUT,
BUT THAT IS JESSE I CAN SEE HIM
MAKING THAT CHOICE AND JUST
DOING SOMETHING.
MY BOY DIED THE WAY I WOULD HAVE
DIED IF I WAS IN THAT POSITION.
SHE SAVED THE LIVES OF THE OTHER
CHILDREN AND TIED THROWING
HERSELF THEY SAID OVER THOSE WHO
RAN OUT INTO THE CLASSROOM.
INCREDIBLE, TRACE, THANK YOU.
WE HAVE TO GET SOME OTHER NEWS
IN TODAY.
THERE IS A LOT GOING ON IN THE
WORLD, AND BECAUSE IT'S JUST
IMPORTANT, IT'S IMPORTANT NOT TO
SPEND ALL DAY EVERY MINUTE ON
THIS.
YOU KNOW, THERE IS ONLY SO MUCH
THE HUMAN SPIRIT CAN TAKE.
WE'LL GET A FEW OTHER SEGMENTS
IN TODAY INCLUDING THIS ONE AND
THAT IS THE OFFICIAL STATE
DEPARTMENT REVIEW ON THE
CIRCUMSTANCES SURROUNDING THAT
SEPTEMBER 11th TERRORIST
ATTACK ON OUR CONSULATE IN
BENGE, LIBYA.
IT'S BEEN COMPLETED AND IT HAS
BEEN DELIVERED TO SECRETARY
CLINTON.
YOU REMEMBER SHE WAS SAYING IN
THE EARLY DAYS, WE ARE GOING TO
WAIT FOR THE REVIEW, WELL IT'S
DONE.
MRS. CLINTON WILL NOT BE
PRESENTING THIS REVIEW TO
CONGRESS AS SHE WAS PLANNING TO
DO DURING THE HEARINGS THIS
WEEK.
THEY SAY IT'S ON DOCTORS ORDERS,
BECAUSE SHE SUFFERED A
CONCUSSION AT SOME POINT LAST
WEEK AFTER FAINTING.
SHE HAD REPORTEDLY HAD THE FLU.
HOUSE FOREIGN AFFAIRS CHAIRWOMAN
HAS MADE IT CLEAR SHE STILL VERY
MUCH WANTS SECRETARY CLINTON TO
TESTIFY AT SOME POINT, SHE
EXPECTS HER TO SHOW UP AND DO SO
AND A PENTAGON SPOKESPERSON
TODAY SAYING THAT SECRETARY
CLINTON IS WILLING TO WORK WITH
THE COMMITTEES ON THAT.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN AND WHERE
DOES IT STAND.
MONICA CROWLEY IS A SYNDICATED
TALK SHOW HOST AND A FOX NEWS
CONTRIBUTOR.
WE APPRECIATE YOU BEING HERE.
>> OF COURSE,.
MEGYN: TO DEVELOP INTO POLITICS
SEEMS LIKE AN ESCAPE FROM THIS
WHOLE STORY RIGHT NOW.
WHAT IS REALLY GOING ON?
STHAO*E SHE FAINTED SOME TIME
LAST WEEK AND CAN'T SHOW UP THIS
THURSDAY FOR A PREVIOUSLY
SCHEDULED TESTIMONY?
THERE WAS SPECULATION I WANT
VIEWERS TO KNOW ABOUT WHETHER
SHE'D REALLY SHOW UP AND DO IT.
>> EVEN BEFORE THE FALL AND THE
CONCUSSION.
MEGYN: I'M NOT SUGGESTING SHE
DIDN'T GET A CONCUSSION.
THERE IS A QUESTION ABOUT DO WE
BELIEVE THIS IS AN SUSAN WILL
SHE SHOW UP TO TESTIFY.
>> THE REASON WE ARE ASKING THE
QUESTIONS ABOUT THIS VIRUS WITH
IMPECCABLE TIMING IS FROM THE
VERY BEGINNING, FROM
SEPTEMBER 11th THE DAY OF THE
ATTACK IN BENGHAZI THAT RESULTED
IN THE DEATHS OF FOUR AMERICAN
CITIZENS THAT WE HAVEN'T BEEN
ABLE TO GET A STRAIGHT STORY OR
FRANKLY ANYBODY FROM THIS
ADMINISTRATION ON THE RECORD
WITH A CLEAR EXPLANATION NOT
JUST FOR THE FOUR FAMILIES BUT
FOR THE AMERICAN PEOPLE.
MEGYN: SHE IS GOING TO SEND SOME
LIEUTENANTS.
IT'S NOT LIKE ALL TESTIMONY HAS
BEEN WITHDRAWN AND WE ARE NOT
GOING TO GET SOMEBODY
KNOWLEDGEABLE WE PRESUME BEFORE
CAPITOL HILL BUT IT'S NOT THE
SECRETARY OF STATE.
AND SHE SAID THE BUCK STOPS WITH
ME.
SO THESE LAWMAKERS WANT TO HEAR
FROM HER, INCLUDING SENATOR KER
RAOEFPLT HE IS THE ONE WHO
REPORTEDLY SAID TO HER DON'T
COME, YOU DON'T FEEL WELL BUT HE
WANTS TO HEAR FROM HER AS WELL
OVER ON THE SENATE SIDE.
>> AND SHE CAN STILL BE CALLED.
EVEN AFTER SHE STEPPED DOWN
PRESUMABLY AND SENATOR KERRY
TAKES HER POSITION SHE CAN STILL
BE CALLED BEFORE THE CONGRESS
AND SHE LIKELY STILL L. BUT THE
PROBLEM IS THAT THIS KIND --
HERE WE ARE ALMOST THREE MONTHS
AFTER THE SEPTEMBER 11th
ATTACKS IN BENGHAZI.
WE ARE STILL AWAITING ANSWERS.
WE STILL CAN'T GET A STRAIGHT
STORY FROM THIS ADMINISTRATION,
AND THOSE WHO ARE IN THE UPPER
LEVELS OF AUTHORITY HERE, WHO
OVERSAW THIS OR AT LEAST HAVE
RESPONSIBILITY FOR IT, INCLUDING
THE SECRETARY OF STATE, NONE OF
OF THEM HAVE PUT THEMSELVES IN A
POSITION BEFORE CONGRESS, BEFORE
THE MEDIA, BEFORE THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE TO ANSWER FOR THIS.
IT'S WHAT I THINK DRAWS A LOT OF
THE FRUSTRATION ON CAPITOL HILL
AND I THINK IN THE PUBLIC.
MEGYN: HOW DOES IT WORK FOR HER
IF JUST HER TOP LIEUTENANTS
TESTIFY AND SHE NEVER DOES?
THIS CONGRESS IS ENDING AT THE
END OF THIS YEAR, WE'LL START A
NEW ONE, AND SHE CAN WE ARE TOLD
BE CALLED BEFORE THE NEW
CONGRESS AND MAY EVEN THOUGH
SHE'LL BE OUT OF A JOB BECAUSE
SHE IS LEAVING HER POSITION AS
SECRETARY OF STATE.
WE SAW THAT WITH WHAT'S HIS
NAME, GENERAL.
>> PETRAEUS.
MEGYN: HE LEFT HIS POST AND WENT
BECOME TO TESTIFY.
HOW LIKELY IS IT THAT SHE WILL
AND HOW MUCH IF ANY DOES THIS
HAVE TO DO WITH HILLARY 2016.
>> I THINK A LOT OF THIS.
SO MUCH OF THIS HAPPENED ON HER
WATCH.
THERE ARE A LOT OF THINGS
PRESUMABLY IN THIS REPORT, THIS
INSPECTOR'S REVIEW REPORT COMING
OUT TODAY THAT WILL BE
TRANSFERRED OVER TO CONGRESS,
MAYBE EVEN MEMBERS OF CONGRESS
HAVE IT NOW TO LOOK AT, THAT
WILL CONTAIN SOME MIGHTY
EMBARRASSING THINGS FOR HER AND
FOR HER DEATH.
UNDERSTANDABLE SHE DOESN'T WANT
TO HAVE TO ANSWER FOR IT.
BUT SHE IS IN THE POSITION OF
AUTHORITY WHERE THE BUCK REALLY
DOES STOP.
THERE ARE SOME POINTS THAT MAYBE
SHE ENDS UP LOOKING VINDICATED
OR ACTUALLY LOOKING OKAY IN ALL
OF THIS.
REMEMBER, IN THE MONTHS LEADING
UP TO THE SEPTEMBER 11th
ATTACKS, MEGYN, SHE AND HER
DEPARTMENT, THE STATE DEPARTMENT
ACTUALLY REQUESTED ON MULTIPLE
OCCASIONS ADDITIONAL SECURITY
FOR BENGHAZI.
THEY WERE TURNED DOWN.
WHO TURNED HER DOWN?
WHO TURNED DOWN THE STATE
DEPARTMENT TO GIVE AMBASSADOR
STEVENS AND THOSE OTHER
AMERICANS ADDED SECURITY?
WAS IT THE WHITE HOUSE?
WELL THERE MAY BE A WHOLE ARRAY
OF THINGS THAT SHE MIGHT NOT
WANT TO ADDRESS.
AGAIN THAT IS UNDERSTANDABLE BUT
SHE IS THE ONE ULTIMATELY
RESPONSIBLE AND SHE DOES HAVE TO
ANSWER FOR THIS AT SOME POINT.
MEGYN: THE REPUBLICANS STILL
CONTROL THE HOUSE, AND WILL IN
JANUARY AS WELL.
IT'S BEEN A BIPARTISAN PUSH IN
THE SENATE TO GET ANSWERS ON
THAT.
EVEN THOUGH THE DEMOCRATS
CONTROL THAT CHAMBER THEY WANTED
ANSWERS FROM SECRETARY CLINTON
NOW AND PRESUMABLY WILL WANT
THEM AFTER THE NEW YEAR.
ANY CHANCE YOU THINK THAT SHE
DOESN'T WIND UP SPEAKING TO
EITHER BODY?
>> I DON'T THINK SO.
I THINK SHE CAN'T AVOID THIS FOR
MUCH LONGER.
I THINK ALL OF THIS IS SORT OF,
THE DELAY IN THE REPORT UNTIL
TODAY, RIGHT BEFORE THE
CHRISTMAS HOLIDAYS.
THEN SHE HAS A STOMACH VIRUS AND
A CONCUSSION AND NOW IT'S
DELAYED EVEN FURTHER.
I THINK PART OF THE STRATEGY IF
THERE IS A STRATEGY HERE IS TO
RUN OUT THE POLITICAL CLOCK SO
MAYBE THE AMERICAN PEOPLE LOSE
INTEREST IN THIS WHICH TH*E
SHOULD NOT, WE HAVE FOUR DEAD
AMERICANS HERE AND WE NEED
ANSWERS ABOUT THAT.
LEADING INTO A NEW
ADMINISTRATION, PRESIDENT
OBAMA'S SECOND TERM, A WHOLE NEW
CAST OF CHARACTERS.
YOU MENTIONED SENATOR KERRY WHO
IS GOING TO SUCCEED HER IN THIS
JOB.
IT'S PROBABLY IN HIS INTERESTS
TO KIND OF SWEEP THIS ASIDE SO
HE CAN BEGIN HIS TENURE ANEW.
ALL OF THIS UNDERSTANDABLE FROM
A POLITICAL STANDPOINT, BUT
REMEMBER AGAIN WE HAVE FOUR DEAD
AMERICANS, FAMILIES NEED
ANSWERS, THE AMERICAN PEOPLE
NEED ANSWERS, AND IN TERMS OF
OUR NATIONAL SECURITY WE NEED TO
KNOW WHAT WENT DOWN AND WHY.
MEGYN: WE HAVE OTHER AMBASSADORS
OUT THERE THAT WE NEED TO WORRY
ABOUT AND MAKE SURE THEY ARE
SAFE AS WELL.
MONICA CROWLEY ALWAYS A
PLEASURE.
>> THANKS.
MEGYN: THERE WERE A NUMBER OF
ANGRY CONFRONTATIONS AFTER THE
RIGHT-TO-WORK VOTE IN MICHIGAN.
NOW WE ARE HEARING HOW ONE UNION
LEADER ISSUED A CONTROVERSIAL
CHALLENGE TO THE MICHIGAN
GOVERNOR THAT SOME ARE SAYING
WAS WAY OVER THE LINE.
LOU DOBBS JOINS US ON THAT IN
THREE MINUTES.
THIS WAS THE HOLE
MY WAIST WAS ON.
BUT SINCE I'VE BEEN ON ALLI,
AM I ON THIS ONE?
NOPE.
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
I AM ON THIS ONE.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR EVERY 2 POUNDS YOU LOSE
THROUGH DIET AND EXERCISE
ALLI CAN HELP YOU LOSE
ONE MORE
BY BLOCKING SOME OF THE FAT
YOU EAT.
SIMPLE. EFFECTIVE.
BELT-FRIENDLY.
LET'S FIGHT FAT WITH ALLI.
HAVE A HEALTHIER HOLIDAY
AT LETSFIGHTHOLIDAYFAT.COM.
MAKE A WISH!
I WISH WE COULD
LIE HERE FOREVER.
I WISH THIS TEST DRIVE WAS OVER,
SO WE COULD HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
TEST DRIVE!
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A JETTA.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN,
$0 DUE AT SIGNING, $0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
MEGYN: PROTESTERS IN
MICHIGAN MAKING IT CLEAR
DESPITE THE STATE'S NEW
RIGHT-TO-WORK LAW THE LABOR
CONVERSATION IS FAR FROM
OVER.
ACTIVISTS REVEREND CHARLES
WILLIAMS II, SPEAKING AT A
PRO-UNION RALLY LAST WEEK
SENT A VERY CLEAR MESSAGE TO
GOVERNOR RICK SNYDER.
LISTEN.
>> JUST NO ONE THING, RICK
SNYDER.
[BLEEP], YOU SIGN THAT BILL,
YOU WILL GET NO REST!.
[CHEERING]
WE GOING TO MEET YOU ON
GETTS ROAD.
WE'LL BE AT YOUR DAUGHTER'S
SOCCER GAME.
WE'LL VISIT YOU AT YOUR
CHURCH.
WE'LL BE AT YOUR OFFICE.
MEGYN: JOINING US KNEW, NOW,
LOU DOBBS, HOST OF LOU TONS
TONIGHT, FOX BUSINESS
NETWORK.
GET AT THISES ROAD, THAT IS
THE ADDRESS OF HIS FAMILY?
>> I'M NOT SURE OF THAT.
MEGYN: WE'LL BE AT YOUR
DAUGHTER'S SOCCER GAME.
WE'LL VISIT YOU AT YOUR
CHURCH, WE'LL BE AT YOUR
OFFICE, ALL IF YOU SIGN THE
BILL SAYING YOU WILL GET NO
REST.
HE DID SIGN THE BILL.
>> WE SHOULD POINT OUT THE
GOVERNOR DAUGHTER'S DOESN'T
PLAY SOCCER.
ENTERPRISING REPORTER FOUND
THAT OUT.
MEGYN: RIGHT.
>> THIS KIND OF LANGUAGE,
THIS KIND OF THUGGERY ON THE
PART OF AN ACTIVIST, WHETHER
UNION ACTIVIST, DESCRIBE HIM
AS OR PASTOR, THIS IS KIND
OF LANGUAGE AGAINST A
BACKDROP OF VIOLENCE WE HAVE
WITNESSED OVER THE COURSE OF
THE LAST SEVERAL WEEKS.
IT IS ABSOLUTELY
INAPPROPRIATE.
AND THE UNIONS ARE BEGINNING
TO ACT, ABSOLUTELY
IRRESPONSIBLY HERE.
THERE IS NO ONE, INCLUDING
THE PRESIDENT HIMSELF WHO IS
THE BENEFICIARY OF MUCH OF
THEIR EFFORTS, SAYING,
PLEASE, ENOUGH WITH THIS
LANGUAGE.
ENOUGH WITH THESE SILLY
ACTIONS.
BEHAVE LIKE MEN AND WOMEN
WHO ARE ADULTS.
MEGYN: CAN I ASK YOU
SOMETHING, LOU?
>> SURE.
MEGYN: THIS COMMENT HAPPENED
BEFORE, I'M TOLD IT HAPPENED
BEFORE FRIDAY.
>> LAST WEEK, YES.
MEGYN: THE MASSACRE IN
NEWTOWN.
>> FOLLOWED THE RIGHT TO
WORK PROTEST.
MEGYN: DOES THAT HAVE ANY
ROLE?
DOES THE NATION HAVE ANY
TOLERANCE FOR THIS TYPE OF
TALK?
WE ARE UPSET WITH YOU AND
WE'LL SHOW UP AT YOUR
CHILD'S SOCCER GAME?
>> I THINK THERE IS TOO MUCH,
IF YOU WILL, TRANSFERNS ON
THE PART OF THE MEDIA.
I DON'T THINK IT IS FAIR TO
SUGGEST IN ANY WAY THE
PASTOR IS RESPONSIBLE FOR
THE DEBT OF 26 INNOCENT
PEOPLE.
MEGYN: NO.
I'M SAYING IS THAT A
GAME-CHANGER IN TERMS OF
TALK IN THE COUNTRY AND
RHETORIC?
>> I DON'T THINK SO.
I DON'T THINK SO.
I THINK WE HAVE FEAR MORE
RESTRAINT OF SPEECH THAN
CONTINUED EXPRESSION.
IS THAT KIND OF SPEECH
APPROPRIATE, INSTANT,
ISOLATED FROM THE VIOLENCE,
THAT IS THE ISSUE.
TO SUGGEST THESE ACTIVISTS
THESE THUGS ARE GOING TO GO
AND WATCH A GOVERNOR'S
DAUGHTERS SPORTS ACTIVITIES?
MEGYN: BE AT YOUR CHURCH.
AT YOUR KID'S EVENTS.
>> THE REPUBLICANS DON'T
HAVE COUNTERVAILING
INFLUENCE ON THAT.
IN POINT OF FACT ON THE
STREET.
THEY DON'T HAVE AN
ORGANIZATION THAT CAN ACT
WITH ABSOLUTE IMPUNITY,
SPEAK IN UGLIEST OF TERMS,
WITH WHICH TO COUNTERACT
THAT KIND OF NONSENSE.
SO THE REPUBLICANS ARE GOING
TO HAVE TO FIGURE OUT A
RESPONSE TO IT BECAUSE THE
PRESIDENT IS NOT LEADING.
THE PRESIDENT IS CAMPAIGNING.
AND SO LONG AS THAT IS THE
CASE, THE REPUBLICANS ARE
GOING TO BE UTTERLY
DEFENSELESS AND ALL THEY
HAVE ON THEIR SIDE IS THE
ABILITY TO, TO BASICALLY
CONDEMN THAT KIND OF
ACTIVITY.
MEGYN: WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF
THAT?
I DON'T KNOW.
ONE THING IS, THERE IS ONE
THING MAKING YOUR POINT
FORCEFULLY.
YOU CAN'T SHUT DOWN ALL
PASSIONATE SPEECH IN THIS
COUNTRY.
>> YOU DON'T HAVE TO.
MEGYN: SPECIFICALLY SPEAKING
WE'LL BE AT YOUR CHILD'S
EVENT.
WE'LL BE AT YOUR CHURCH.
THAT IS THERNOR'S ANN
ARBOR RESIDENCE, THAT GETTIES
ROAD.
SHOULD WE AS NEWS
ORGANIZATIONS TALKING ABOUT
THIS?
OTHERWISE IS GOES TOTALLY
IGNORED AND THERE IS NO
ACCOUNTABILITY.
WHAT ARE YOUR THOUGHTS ON
THAT?
>> MY THOUGHTS ARE WE BETTER
BE TALKING ABOUT.
THANK GOD FOR FOX NEWS AND
OTHERWISE, NO ONE WOULD BE
TALKING ABOUT THESE ISSUES
EXCEPT FROM THE LEFT'S
PERSPECTIVE.
THAT WOULD BE A GREAT SHAME.
MEGYN: LOU DOBBS, THANK YOU.
COMING UP WE EXPECT ANOTHER
NEWS CONFERENCE.
DON'T GO AWAY.
I'VE GOTINE GRAMS OF PROTEIN.
THAT'S THREE TIMES MORE THAN ME!
[ Female Announcer ]
Ensure Clear.
NINE GRAMS PROTEIN. ZERO FAT.
IN BLUEBERRY/POMEGRANATE
AND PEACH.
FLAVOR BOOST, MEET BEEF.
IT'S SWANSON FLAVOR BOOST.
CONCENTRATED BROTH
TO ADD DELICIOUS FLAVOR
TO YOUR SKILLET DISH
IN JUST ONE STIR.
MMM!
[ Female Announcer ]
COOK, MEET COMPLIMENTS.
GET RECIPES AT FLAVORBOOST.COM.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
♪ .
MEGYN: WELL THE WHITE HOUSE
MADE SOME ADDITIONAL REMARKS
ON GUN CONTROL MOMENTS AGO
IN THE AFTERMATH OF THE
NEWTOWN SHOOTING.
WE HOPE TO HAVE THOSE
REMARKS IN A MOMENT.
WE HAVE BEEN MONITORING THAT
PRESS SER.
BUT TO GIVE YOU A SENSE OF
THE MOOD IN CONNECTICUT,
EARLIER TODAY POLICE IN THE
CITY OF RIDGEFIELD ORDERED
SCHOOLS ON LOCKDOWN BECAUSE
OF UNSPECIFIED, QUOTE,
INCIDENT.
THEY GAVE THE GREEN LIGHT TO
BE OPEN WITH A POLICE
PRESENCE REMAINING IN EACH
PLACE AT SCHOOL.
RIDGEFIELD IS 20 MILES AWAY
FROM NEWTOWN.
A LOT OF FOLKS ON EDGE
TODAY.
>>> ROUGHLY 5:00 P.M. THIS
EVENING TWO NASA SPACESHIPS
WILL CRASH HEAD LONG INTO
THE MOON, ON PURPOSE.
TRACE GALLAGHER EXPLAINS
WHY.
TRACE?
>> Reporter:, WELL THE
FIREWORKS, MEGYN BECAUSE
THEY BOTH RAN OUT OF GAS,
RIGHT?
THAT'S WHY THEY HAVE TO BE
CRASHED.
THESE TWO ORBITERS, TWIN
ORBITERS WILL HIT IMPACT
ABOUT 5:28 EAST COAST TIME
TONIGHT.
THEY WILL CONTINUE MAPPING
THE MOON.
THEY'RE GOING OUT WITH A
FIGHT, MAPPING THE MOON
UNTIL THE MOMENT OF IMPACT.
THAT WILL HAPPEN ABOUT 30
SECONDS APART AND THEY WILL
CRASH AT AN ESTIMATED 3700
MILES PER HOUR.
THESE ORBITERS BY THE WAY
WERE LAUNCHED BACK IN
SEPTEMBER OF 2011.
THEY SPENT MORE THAN A YEAR
GOING AROUND AND MAPPING THE
MOON'S CRATERS AND GRAVITY
FORCE FIELD, CHECKING OUT
THE MOON'S DENSITY WHICH IS
FASCINATING THE CRUST IS
LESS DENSE THAN WE THOUGHT
WHICH IS BIG SUPPORT TO THE
THEORY, BILLIONS OF YEARS
AGO THE MOON WAS CREATED
BECAUSE THE EARTH AND A
PLANET ABOUT THE SIZE OF
MARS ACTUALLY COLLIDED,
CREATING THAT MOON AND EB
WILL CRASH FIRST FOLLOWED BY
FLO.
THERE WILL NOT BE LIVE
PICTURES BECAUSE NASA SAYS
IT IS GOING INTO AN AREA OF
THE MOON KIND OF SHADED IN
THE SHADOWS.
IF THEY COULD ONLY FIND A
GAS STATION UP THERE, MEGYN.
THEY WOULD BE FINE.
THEY'RE IN PERFECT SHAPE.
THEY COULD KEEP FLYING
AROUND.
THERE IS OUT OF FUEL AND NO
WAY TO REFUEL THEM.
RIGHT.
MEGYN: TOO BAD.
THEY DOESN'T FORESEE ANY
DAMAGE TO US IN THIS PLANNED
CRASH?
>> Reporter: NO.
THEY'RE HITTING THE NORTH
POLE.
THE REASON THEY'RE DOING
THAT BECAUSE THEY WANT THE
THINGS AS FAR AWAY FROM THE
PREVIOUS SPACE JUNK, THE
STUFF WE LEFT UP THERE
PRIOR.
THEY DON'T WANT THESE
CONFUSED WITH ANY TYPE OF
MOON LANDING OR ANY OF THAT
NONSENSE.
OTHER SIDE OF THE PLANET.
MEGYN: TRACE, THANKS.
>> Reporter: OKAY.
MEGYN: COMING UP IN THE
AFTERMATH OF THE NEWTOWN
NANCY LANZA'S FRIENDS ARE
TELLING THE WORLD ABOUT
CHALLENGES SHE HAD WITH
ADAM.
THERE IS SOME QUESTION WHAT
HIS MENTAL ORDER, DEFECT, IF
ANY REALLY WAS.
WE'LL SPEAK WITH SOME MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS ABOUT
THAT ISSUE COMING UP.
MELL
OF A GOOD TIME.
THIS IS THE JUNIPER!
OH THAT IS MAGICAL.
[ Male Announcer ] WHEN YOU
COMBINE CREAMY VELVEETA
WITH ZESTY ROTEL TOMATOES
AND GREEN CHILES,
YOU'LL GET A BOWL OF QUESO
THAT MAKES EVEN
THIS GET-TOGETH BETTER.
to the number 1 club
in the world.
The potential of
Manchester United unlocked.
NYSE Euronext.
Unlocking the world's potential.
MEGYN: THIS IS A FOX NEWS
ALERT.
NEW REACTION FROM THE
WHITE HOUSE THIS HOUR TO THE
TRAGIC MASS SHOOTING IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
BRAND NEW HOUR HERE OF
"AMERICA LIVE", WELCOME,
EVERYONE.
I'M MEGYN KELLY.
WE HAVE NEW VIDEO FROM THE
GROWING MEMORIALS IN
NEWTOWN.
THE FIRST FUNERAL SERVICES
WERE SCHEDULED TO START
ABOUT AN HOUR AGO.
TWO 6-YEAR-OLD BOYS LAID TO
REST AFTER A CRIME THE
PRESIDENT SAYS REMINDS JUST
HOW PRECIOUS AND FRAGILE,
LOOK AT THOSE FACES A
PARENT'S RELATIONSHIP WITH
THEIR CHILD CAN BE.
>> THERE IS ONLY ONE THING
WE CAN BE SURE OF.
AND THAT IS THE LOVE THAT WE
HAVE.
FOR OUR CHILDREN, FOR OUR
FAMILIES, FOR EACH OTHER.
THE WARMTH OF A SMALL
CHILD'S EMBRACE.
THAT IS TRUE.
THE MEMORIES WE HAVE OF THEM,
THE JOY THAT THEY BRING, THE
WONDER WE SEE THROUGH THEIR
EYES.
THAT FIERCE AND BOUNDLESS
LOVE WE FEEL FOR THEM.
A LOVE THAT TAKES US OUT OF
OURSELVES AND BIND US TO
SOMETHING LARGER.
WE KNOW THAT'S WHAT MATTERS.
WE KNOW WE'RE ALWAYS DOING
RIGHT WHEN WE'RE TAKING CARE
OF THEM.
WHEN WE'RE TEACHING THEM
WELL.
WHEN WE'RE SHOWING ACTS OF
KINDNESS.
WE DON'T GO WRONG WITH THEY
DO THAT.
MEGYN: EVERY PARENT CAN
RELATE TO THOSE WORDS.
I MEAN EVERY PARENT HELD
THEIR CHILD A LITTLE TIGHTER
THIS WEEKEND.
AND WAS REMINDED TO JUST
TREASURY THE LOVE YOU HAVE
FOR YOUR BABIES, RIGHT?
CHIEF CORRESPONDENT ED HENRY
IS LIVE AT THE WHITE HOUSE
WITH MORE.
AND THERE WAS A QUESTION, NO
ONE QUESTIONED CERTAINLY
ANYTHING THE PRESIDENT SAID
ALONG THOSE LINES, ED.
HE WENT ON TO TALK ABOUT
WHAT NEEDS TO HAPPEN IN THE
COUNTRY AND HE DIDN'T GET
SPECIFIC.
CLEARLY SOMETHING NEEDS TO
HAPPEN.
>> Reporter: NO DOUBT ABOUT
IT, MEGYN.
I WAS THERE WITH THE
PRESIDENT LAST NIGHT,
SPEAKING TO PEOPLE IN THE
COMMUNITY.
SOME OF THEM TOLD ME THAT
THEY WALKED FOR ABOUT ONE
HOUR IN A VERY COLD RAIN
THERE IN NEWTOWN BECAUSE ALL
THE PARKING AROUND THAT HIGH
SCHOOL WAS ALL FILLED UP.
THE AUDITORIUM, FULL.
PEOPLE WERE THAT COMMITTED
TO TURNING OUT AND TRYING TO
DO TWO THINGS.
TRYING TO GRIEVE AND MOURN
AND HELP HEAL THE PEOPLE WHO
HAVE BEEN SO HURT IN THAT
COMMUNITY BUT SECONDLY THEY
WERE WONDERING WHAT'S NEXT
HERE.
AND YOU'RE RIGHT, THE
PRESIDENT DID IN GENERAL
REFER TO THE IDEA IT WAS
SORT OF A CALL TO ACTION IN
THE MIDDLE OF THAT SPEECH
LAST NIGHT.
IT WAS BASICALLY, LIKE, WE
HAVE NOT DONE ENOUGH TO
PROTECT OUR CHILDREN.
HE WAS HINTING AT GUN
CONTROL, OTHER MEASURES
POTENTIALLY, BUT AS YOU SAY
HE DIDN'T GET SPECIFIC.
A FW MOMENTS AGO JAY CARNEY
IN THE BRIEFING GOT A LOT OF
QUESTIONS ABOUT THIS.
REPORTERS PRESSING ABOUT
WHAT ACTION THE PRESIDENT
WILL ACTUALLY TAKE.
HE WAS PRETTY VAGUE ABOUT
DETAILS.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> IT'S A COMPLEX PROBLEM
THAT WILL REQUIRE A COMPLEX
SOLUTION.
NO SINGLE PIECE OF
LEGISLATION, NO SINGLE
ACTION WILL FULLY ADDRESS
THE PROBLEM.
>> Reporter: JAY CARNEY DID
SAY SPECIFICALLY THAT THE
PRESIDENT STILL SUPPORTS
SOMETHING THAT HE HAD SAID,
HE SUPPORTED GOING BACK TO
THE 2008 PRESS 2008
PRESIDENTIAL CAMPAIGN
RENEWING THE BAN ON ASSAULT
WEAPONS WHICH EXPIRED.
PRESIDENT SPOKE OUT
PREVIOUSLY WHAT HE CALLED
WEAPONS OF WAR OFF THE
STREETS.
THAT IS ONE SPECIFIC.
BUT THEN PRESSED FOR MORE
DETAILS HOW QUICKLY THE
PRESIDENT WILL ACT, HE
REALLY DIDN'T WANT TOO GET
INTO THAT.
THAT WILL BE THE QUESTION
MOVING FORWARD, HOW MUCH
PEOPLE ARE TALKING, WHAT
KIND OF ACTION WILL HAPPEN.
MEGYN?
MEGYN: ED HENRY, THANK YOU.
WE WANT TO GO TO THE
WHITE HOUSE TO THE U.S.
SENATE WHERE THERE IS MOMENT
OF SILENCE FOR THE VICTIMS
OF NEWTOWN.
[MOMENT OF SILENCE]
>> MR. PRESIDENT?
>> MAJORITY LEADER.
>> REMARKS THE SENATE WILL
BE IN MORNING BUSINESS.
MEGYN: SENATE MAJORITY
LEADER HARRY REID SPEAKING.
THIS IS ONE OF THOSE
MOMENTS.
IT IS LIKE, WHAT THE COUNTRY
FELT AFTER 9/11 WHERE
REGARDLESS OF YOUR POLITICS
YOU FEEL FIRST AN AMERICAN,
YOU FEEL FIRST A PARENT, AND
YOU THINK, IT DOESN'T MATTER
WHAT YOUR PARTY AFFILIATION
IS.
WE HAVE TO WORK TOGETHER TO
BE HONEST ABOUT WHAT LED TO
THIS.
AND HOW TO STOP IT FROM
HAPPENING AGAIN.
WITHOUT ANY QUICK FIXES,
WITHOUT ANY QUICK JUDGMENTS
TO REALLY LOOK AT IT, TRY TO
FIGURE IT OUT.
YOU CAN SEE SOME BIPARTISAN
SHARING IN THE HEARTBREAK
THERE ON CAPITOL HILL
MOMENTS AGO.
AMID THE TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN
THERE ARE AMAZING STORIES OF
HEROISM.
HAVE BEEN SO MOVING, JUST
RENEW YOUR BELIEF IN THE
HUMAN SPIRIT, DON'T THEY?
WE HAVE TO HOLD ONTO THAT.
THIS COUNTRY, BEING AN
AMERICAN, BEING A HUMAN
BEING ON THIS EARTH IS NOT
IDENTIFYING WITH ADAM LANZA.
IT IS ABOUT IDENTIFYING WITH
VICTORIA SOTO AND THAT
BEAUTIFUL PRINCIPAL AND ALL
THE OTHERS IN THAT SCHOOL
THAT DID SO OF MUCH TO SAVE
LIVES, AND TO PROTECT
CHILDREN.
THAT'S WHAT WE DO.
YET WE'RE LEARNING MORE
ABOUT THIS CASE AND THIS
INVESTIGATION.
AND TRACE GALLAGHER JOINS US
LIVE WITH MORE.
TRACE?
>> Reporter: THERE ARE SOME
HEROES THROUGHOUT THIS,
MEGYN, YOU NEVER GET A
CHANCE TO TALK ABOUT.
YOU MENTIONED THE PRINCIPAL.
HER NAME IS DAWN HOCHSPRUNG.
ON 9:40 IN THE MORNING WE
ARE LEARNING SHE CAME OUT OF
THE MEETING.
SHE STEPPED INTO THE HALL.
SHE SAW THE GUNMAN.
SHE TURNED AROUND AND HER
COLLEAGUES TO LOCK THE DOOR
AND THEY DID.
PSYCHOLOGIST, 56-YEAR-OLD
MARY SHERLACH AND WENT
DIRECTLY TOWARD THE GUNMAN
AND LUNGED AT HIM.
THEY WERE APPARENTLY THE
FIRST TWO SHOT AND KILLED.
LISTEN NOW TO THE
PRINCIPAL'S COUSIN.
>> WHEN I LEARNED SHE
ACTUALLY TRIED TO TAKE THE
GUNMAN DOWN, IT WAS NO
SURPRISE TO ME AT ALL.
MY ONLY HOPE THE GUNMAN HAD
A LITTLE BIT OF FEAR KNOWING
THIS 5'2" INCH "RAGING BULL"
IS COMING AT I AM AND HE HAD
A LITTLE BIT OF FEAR IN HIS
EYES KNOWING SOMEONE LIKE
DUNE WAS COMING AFTER HIM
BECAUSE HE WAS TRYING TO
HURT HER STUDENTS.
>> Reporter: EVERYBODY WHO
KNEW THE PRINCIPAL SAID SHE
WAS IN FACT 10 NASH SCHUSS.
40-YEAR-OLD TEACHER NATALIE
HAMMOND WAS IN THE MEETING.
WHEN THE PRINCIPAL RAN
TOWARD THE GUNMAN, SHE USED
HER BODY TO BLOCK THE
ENTRANCE TO THE OFFICE.
SHE IS SHOT AND WOUNDED AND
WILL LIKELY SURVIVE AND
LIKELY MADE SURE OTHERS ALSO
SURVIVED.
THERE IS THE TEACHER CAITLIN
ROY.
SHE BARRICADED HER 15
STUDENTS INTO A TINY
BATHROOM.
PULLED A BOOKSHELF ACROSS
THE DOOR.
SHE TOLD THE STUDENTS THERE
WERE BAD GUYS OUTSIDE AND
THEY HAD TO WAIT FOR THE
GOOD GUYS TO GET THERE.
HER CLASSROOM WOULD HAVE
BEEN THE FIRST ONE ADAM
LANZA REACHED AND YET FOR
MANY SOME REASON HE WALKED
RIGHT BY IT, PASSED IT BY.
NOBODY KNOWS WHY.
MORE THAN 650 STUDENTS AS WE
SAID AND TEACHERS GOT OUT OF
THERE.
YOU LOOK AT THIS WOMEN'S
FACE AND YOU LOOK AT OTHER'S
IN THERE AND THERE ARE
REASONS SO MUCH SURVIVED AND
HE HAD SO MANY ROUNDS OF
WEAPON, OF AMMUNITION LEFT
STILL LEFT IN THOSE GUNS.
MEGYN: THOSE TEACHERS SAVED
LIVES THAT DAY.
THAT SEEMS ABSOLUTELY CLEAR.
THE TEACHERS AND
ADMINISTRATORS DID SAVE
LIVES.
GOD BLESS THE
FIRST-RESPONDERS WHO BELIEVE
HE KILLED HIMSELF WHEN THEY
WERE COMING IN.
HE WAS FULLY PREPARED TO
UNLEASH MORE CARNAGE AND
THEY GOT THERE SO QUICKLY.
UNFORTUNATELY NOT QUICKLY
ENOUGH.
TRACE, THANKS.
>>> THE TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN
NOT ONLY LEAVING ITS MARK ON
THE RESIDENTS THERE BUT AS I
MENTIONED ON THE
FIRST-RESPONDERS WHO ARRIVED
JUST MOMENTS AFTER THE
SHOOTING.
COMING UP HOW THEY'RE
DEALING WITH THE TRAGEDY
THREE DAYS LATER.
AS WE LEARN MORE ABOUT THE
SHOOTER, WE
ABOUT THE CHALLENGES THAT
HIS MOTHER FACED RAISING A
SON DESCRIBED AS DISTANT AND
SOCIALLY AWKWARD AND REPORTS
THAT HIS STRUGGLE, HIS
MENTAL STRUGGLE, WHATEVER
WAS AFFECTING HIM, SEEMED TO
HAVE BEEN GETTING WORSE IN,
IN THE YEARS, THE LAST
COUPLE OF YEARS.
AND A FRIEND OF THE MOTHER
IS SPEAKING ABOUT THE
STRUGGLE THAT UNITED THIS
MAN AND NANCY LANZA.
>> NANCY WOULD GET UPSET
BECAUSE HER SON REFUSED TO
LET HER TOUCH HIM.
SHE COULDN'T HUG HIM.
WHERE MY SON IS JUST THE
OPPOSITE.
SHE WOULD SEE MY SON HANGING
ALL OVER ME BUT, YOU KNOW,
AUTISTIC KIDS, EACH AND
EVERYONE OF THEM IS
DIFFERENT
QUESTIONS?
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
HI VICTOR!
MOM?
I KNOW YOU GOT TO GO
IN A MINUTE
BUT THIS IS
A REAL QUICK ME,
THAT'S PERFECT FOR TWO!
CAMPBELL'S CHUNKY BEEF
WITH COUNTRY VEGETABLES,
POURED OVER RICE!
[ Male Announcer ]
CAMPBELL'S CHUNKY SOUP.
IT FILLS YOU UP RIGHT.
YOU CAN STAY IN
AND SHARE SOMETHING...
OR YOU CAN GET OUT THERE
AND ACTUALLY SHARE SOMETHING.
♪
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
MEGYN: WE ARE LEARNING MORE
TODAY ABOUT ONE OF THE
VICTIMS IN TRAGEDY IN
PARTICULAR.
THE PARENTS OF 6-YEAR-OLD
JESSICA REKOS SAT DOWN WITH
AN INTERVIEW EARLIER TODAY
WITH ABC NEWS.
REMEMBERING THE LITTLE GIRL
THEY LOVED SO MUCH.
FEW OF THE PARENTS HAVE
SPOKEN OUT.
THIS IS THE SECOND SET THAT
HAVE GONE OUT ON CAMERA.
AND THE PAIN THEY FELT IN
LEARNING THAT THE LIGHT OF
THEIR LIVES WAS TAKEN BY A
GUNMAN IN FRIDAY'S MASSACRE.
I WANT TO WARN YOU THIS IS
VERY EMOTIONAL BUT VERY
POWERFUL AND JESSICA'S
PARENTS WANT THE WORLD TO
HEAR THEIR STORY.
>> SHE WAS A BALL OF FIRE.
SHE RULED THE ROOST.
>> A LITTLE CEO WE CALLED
HER.
SHE WAS, SHE WAS THE BOSS.
>> I GOT TO THE FIREHOUSE.
>> WE HAD NO IDEA AT THAT
POINT, WE THOUGHT, OKAY, THE
REPORTS ARE ONE OR TWO
PEOPLE MAY HAVE BEEN
INJURED.
>> WALKED DOWN TO THE
FIREHOUSE.
MAYBE SHE IS IN THERE.
MAYBE SHE IS THERE.
>> I MUST HAVE DONE 100
LAPS.
>> I KNEW EXACTLY WHAT SHE
WAS WEARING.
WOULD SEE THE LITTLE
PONYTAIL COME AROUND THE
CORNER AND HER JACKET AND
BLACK GETTERRY -- GLITERY
GLOVES.
FINALLY 1:15, ASKED
EVERYBODY TO SIT DOWN AND
THEY SAID THAT IT WAS A
TRAGIC DAY IN NEWTOWN TODAY
AND 20 CHILDREN WERE KILLED.
AND, PLEASE DON'T TELL ME MY
LITTLE GIRL WAS GONE.
>> THERE WAS SO MUCH PAIN
AND CONFUSION WHEN THE
ANNOUNCEMENT WAS MADE OF THE,
THE LIFE WAS SUCKED OUT OF
EVERYONE IN THE ROOM.
AND YOU KNOW, AT THIS POINT
I FOUND A STATE TROOPER, ARE
THERE ANY SURVIVES?
ARE YOU TELLING ME STANDING
HERE AS A PARENT MY CHILD IS
GONE?
AND HE SAID YES.
>> SHE JUST GOT --
[INAUDIBLE]
AND, STILL NOT REAL, THAT MY
LITTLE GIRL WHO WAS SO FULL
OF LIFE AND WHO WANT AS
HORSE SO BADLY AND WHO IS
GOING TO GET COWGIRL BOOTS
FOR CHRISTMAS ISN'T COME
HOME.
MEGYN: AND THAT'S WHAT YOU
WOULD DO, ISN'T IT.
YOU GET INTO THIS CHILD'S
BED AND YOU REMEMBER ALL THE
THINGS YOU LOVED ABOUT THEM.
ABC NEWS DID A GREAT JOB
WITH THE INTERVIEW.
WE APPRECIATE THE, THEM
LETTING US RUN THAT CLIP AND,
BUT THE EMOTION THAT YOU
FEEL WHEN YOU WATCH THAT
STORY AND YOU FEEL THAT
STORY AND YOU FEEL ALL THE
STORIES THAT WE'VE ALL BEEN
GOING THROUGH THE PAST 72
HOURS RELATE DIRECTLY TO
WHAT WE'LL TALK TO OUR NEXT
GUEST ABOUT.
DR. MARK SIEGEL IS HERE.
HE IS PART OF OUR MEDICAL
A-TEAM HERE AT FOX NEWS.
AND THERE'S SOMETHING IN US
THAT MAKES US NEED TO HEAR
THOSE STORIES, RIGHT?
IT IS TERRIBLE AND HARD.
I'M TEARING UP LISTENING TO
IT.
I'M SURE A LOT OF VIEWERS
ARE TOO.
YOU WANT PEOPLE TO KNOW, WE
CAN'T DO TOO MUCH OF THAT.
IT IS STILL VERY EARLY BUT
WE CAN'T DO TOO MUCH OF
THAT.
WHY?
>> MEGYN, WE HAVE DEEP
EMOTIONAL CENTERS IN OUR
BRAIN THAT WE GET FROM OUR
ANIMAL FOREBEARERS AND WE
HAVE TO WATCH WHAT EMOTIONS
GO THROUGH THAT.
INEVITABLY IF WE WATCH TV
WE'LL GET CERTAIN EMOTIONS.
WE HEARD TRACE GALLAGHER
GIVE THE AMAZING REPORT
ABOUT THE COURAGE OF THE
PRINCIPAL AND TEACHER.
THAT GIVES US COURAGE.
WE HEAR ABOUT THE PARENT
THAT LOST A CHILD.
YOU AND I ARE SITTING HERE
THAT WE HAVE YOUNG CHILDREN
AND MOST IMPORTANT THING IN
OUR LIVES.
WE DON'T NEED FEAR.
WE NEED EMPATHY.
WE NEED TO CARE FOR HER AND
PASSION FOR HER.
THAT'S WHAT WE NEED TO TEACH
OUR CHILDREN, WE NEED
COURAGE, EMPATHY, NOT FEAR.
STATISTICALLY CHANCES OF IT
HAPPENING, THANK GOD TO ONE
OF OUR CHILDREN IS EXTREMELY
LOW EVEN STILL.
MEGYN: THAT IS THE THING YOU
HAVE TO REMEMBER, EVEN IN
THE WAKE OF THIS, THE ODDS
OF THIS HAPPENING IT YOU AND
YOUR FAMILY ARE INIF I TEST
MALL.
>> I GIVE YOU STATISTICS.
HOMICIDES TO SCHOOL-AGE
CHILDREN ONLY OCCUR AROUND
SCHOOLS LESS THAN ONE
PERCENT OF THE TIME.
HERE IS ANOTHER THING.
ELIZABETH FELLSPS FROM NYU,
MEASURED THE BRAIN, IF
YOU'RE WATCHING SOMEONE HURT
LIKE THIS YOU HAVE THE SAME
REACTION IF IT WAS HAPPENING
TO YOU.
THAT IS WHY WE HAVE TO LIMIT
THE AMOUNT OF CONTACT OUR
CHILDREN HAVE WITH THESE
IMAGES.
MEGYN: AND THAT WE HAVE WITH
THESE IMAGES POTENTIALLY.
IF YOU AS THE DAD OR I AS
THE MOM COME HOME WITH ALL
OF THIS ON US, I MEAN, YOU
KNOW, KIDS ARE PERCEPTIVE.
THEY FEEL IT.
THEY, SAY SORT OF LIKE,
MOM'S IN A BAD MOOD,
EVERYBODY IS IN A BAD MOOD.
YOU HAVE TO WATCH THAT.
>> SO TRUE.
IF WE WORRY, THEY WORRY.
IF WE'RE CALM, THEY'RE CALM.
IF WE COME HOME TALKING
ABOUT THAT PRINCIPAL,
THEY'RE GOING TO UNDERSTAND
COURAGE, YOU KNOW.
WE OF COURSE HAVE TO FEEL
THE FOR THE VICTIMS.
THEN THERE IS THE ISSUE OF
SURVIVES.
THERE WILL BE A VERY HIGH
INCIDENCE OF POST-TRAMATIC
STRESS DISORDER.
MEGYN: WHAT ABOUT THAT?
THEY WILL HAVE POST-TRAMATIC
STRESS.
WILL THE NATION HAVE
POST-TRAMATIC STRESS.
>> WE HAVE MORE CONTROL.
THOSE CHILDREN WILL HAVE IT.
THEY WILL FEEL SAD.
THEY WILL FEEL ANGRY.
THEY WON'T FEEL THEMSELVES
FOR A LONG TIME.
SURVIVORS OF COLUMBINE BIND
ARE NEVER THEMSELVES.
THEY HAVE FLASHBACKS.
THE NATION CAN CONTROL WHAT
WE HAVE IT IS NOT OUR
CHILDREN.
WE CAN FEEL COMPASSION AND
CARING AND IT IS NOT OUR
CHILDREN.
AS LONG AS IT IS NOT WE CAN
LIMIT THE AMOUNT OF
POST-TRAUMATIC STRESS WE
HAVE.
THERE IS PHENOMENON CALLED
VICARIOUS TRAUMATIC STRESS
DISORDER.
WE CAN GET IT FROM WATCHING
TOO MUCH OF THIS.
MEGYN: HOW IMPORTANT IS IT
IN THE WAKE OF SOMETHING
LIKE THIS FOR PEOPLE TO
REMEMBER, HERE WE ARE IN THE
CHRISTMAS SEASON, HAND CALL
AS WELL, THE INFLUX OF
POSITIVE ENERGY, POSITIVE
STORIES OF THINGS THAT JUST
MAKE YOU FEEL GOOD.
CHRISTMAS SEASON.
WE WATCHED "WHITE CHRISTMAS"
OVER THE WEEKEND.
SOMETHING LIGHT THAT MAKES
YOU SMILE, FEEL GOOD.
HOW IMPORTANT IS THAT RIGHT
NOW?
>> HUGE.
THE CARING COME OUT OF THIS
ALREADY, PASTOR AND RABBI
THE WAY THEY'RE BRINGING
PEOPLE TOGETHER.
THE LOVE AND OUTPOURING AND
CARE FROM THE U.S..
THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES'S REACTION TO THIS,
ALL OF THE REACTIONS ON A
POSITIVE NOTE OF COMPASSION
AND CARING COMING INTO THE
CHRISTMAS SEASON, THE
HANUKKAH SEASON THAT'S WHAT
WE NEED.
MEGYN: YOU CAN'T SKIP PAST
THE GRIEF.
YOU CAN'T DO THAT NOTHING
WILL CHANGE.
WE WON'T TAKE A CLOSE LOOK
HOW THIS HAPPENED.
THEN YOU HAVE TO MOVE ON
FROM IT.
>> WELL, MEGYN, I WANT TO
SAY, THIS IS A SERIES OF
TERRIBLE PERSONAL TRAGEDIES.
IT IS NOT A NATIONAL
TRAGEDY.
IT IS A PERSONAL TRAGEDY.
>> I DON'T KNOW ABOUT THAT,
DOC.
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT THAT.
>> IT IS A NATIONAL TRAGEDY
IN THE SENSE WE'RE MOURNING
FOR THEM.
MEGYN: IN A SENSE SEEMS LIKE
THE WORLD GOT A LITTLE
DARKER ON FRIDAY.
I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE SAYING IT
DIDN'T HAPPEN TO US.
WE DIDN'T LOSE CHILDREN,
THANK GOD.
THE FACT THAT THERE IS, I
DON'T KNOW EVEN IF I KNOW I
WANT TO SAY EVIL.
I DON'T KNOW WHETHER THIS
YOUNG MAN WAS EVIL OR SO
DISTURBED THAT HE DID AN
EVIL THING AND WENT TO AN
EVIL PLACE.
THAT IS FOR THE
PSYCHIATRISTS TO FIGURE OUT.
BUT I MEAN, IT JUST SEEMS
LIKE WE LOST A HAIL BIT OF
OURSELVES SOMEHOW ON FRIDAY.
A RED LINE WAS CROSSED AS
DR. ABLOW SAID WE DIDN'T
THINK COULD BE CROSSED.
>> MEGYN, IN TERMS OF MENTAL
HEALTH FOR A SECOND, THERE
ARE MANY, MANY PEOPLE OUT
THERE WITH THIS KIND OF
PSYCHIATRIC DISTURBANCE.
WE DON'T HAVE A LOT OF
FACTS.
PHYSICIAN FRENCH YAW,
DELUSIONAL SYSTEM, WHATEVER
HE HAD WAS PRETTY BAD MENTAL
ILLNESS THERE ARE PLENTY OF
PEOPLE OUT THERE WITH THESE
CONDITIONS NOT COMMITTING
CRIMES.
MEGYN: MOST OF THEM.
WE'LL TALK MORE ABOUT THAT
IN A LITTLE BIT.
DR. SIEGEL THANKS FOR BEING
HERE.
>> THANK YOU.
MEGYN: AT THIS TIME OF YEAR,
WE LOVE TO WATCH CHRISTMAS
IN CONNECTICUT.
HAVE YOU SEEN THAT CHRISTMAS
MOVIE?
SEEMS LIKE YOU NEED
SOMETHING, SOME SOOTHING
BALM TO TAKE YOUR MIND OFF
IT AND REMIND YOURSELVES
THINGS YOU DO THIS TIME OF
YEAR TO MAKE YOU AND YOUR
FAMILY FEEL GREAT.
IN THE AFTERMATH OF NEWTOWN,
NANCY LANZA, THAT WAS THE
MOTHER, SHE IS TELLING THE
WORLD ABOUT THE CHALLENGES
WITH HER SON ADAM, WHO WAS
DESCRIBED AS SOCIALLY
AWKWARD AND TROUBLED.
HE ALSO HAD SOME TYPE OF
AUTISM.
WE HAVE A EX-PERIOD OF TIME
NOT JUST ON AUTISM AND
MENTAL ILLNESS WHICH AUTISM
IS NOT AND WE TALK ABOUT
WHERE WE GO FROM HERE IN
TERMS OF DIAGNOSES THAT CAN
PROTECT US ALL.
ALLY BANK.
WHY THEY HAVE A
RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
TONIGHT OUR GUEST,
THOMAS SARGENT.
NOBEL LAUREATE
IN ECONOMICS,
AND ONE OF THE MOST CITED
ECONOMISTS IN THE WORLD.
PROFESSOR SARGENT,
CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT CD RATES WILL
BE IN TWO YEARS?
NO.
IF HE CAN'T, NO ONE CAN.
THAT'S WHY ALLY HAS
A RAISE YOUR RATE CD.
ALLY BANK.
YOUR MONEY NEEDS AN ALLY.
HI,
I'M Ensure Clear...
Clear, HUH?
I'M NOT JUICE OR FANCY WATER.
I'VE GOTINE GRAMS OF PROTEIN.
THAT'S THREE TIMES MORE THAN ME!
[ Female Announcer ]
Ensure Clear.
NINE GRAMS PROTEIN. ZERO FAT.
IN BLUEBERRY/POMEGRANATE
AND PEACH.
WASHINGTON BECAUSE PRESIDENT
OBAMA IS EXPECTED TO
ANNOUNCE HIS NEW FOREIGN
POLICY TEAM SOON AND THERE
IS GROWING SPECULATION THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL TAB A
FORMER REPUBLICAN SENATOR TO
BE HIS NEXT SECRETARY OF
DEFENSE, SENATOR CHUCK
HAGEL.
EVEN BEFORE THAT HAPPENS
THERE IS GROWING ANGER FROM
SOME JEWISH GROUPS IS
MR. HAGEL'S PAST HOSTILITY
TOWARDS ISRAEL AND ITS
INTERESTS.
JOHN BOLTON, FORMER YOU KNOW
AMBASSADOR TO THE UNITED
NATIONS AND AMBASSADOR GET
TO HAVE YOU HERE.
FORMER MAYOR OF NEW YORK
ED KOCH SPOKE OUT IN
PARTICULAR AND TALKED ABOUT
CHUCK HAGEL'S PERCEIVED
HOSTILITY TOWARD ISRAEL AND
SAYING IT WOULD BE A
TERRIBLE APPOINTMENT AND
APPARENTLY MOST OF THE
JEWISH LEADERS WHO HAVE
EXPRESSED THEMSELVES.
WHY?
>> I THINK THEY HAVE LOOKED
AT A NUMBER OF VOTES THAT
SENATOR HAGEL TOOK DURING
HIS TIME IN THE SENATE AND
THEY'RE VERY WORRIED WHAT
HIS POSITION ON ISRAEL,
TERRORISM IN THE MIDDLE
EAST.
DEALING WITH IRAN WOULD BE.
LET ME SAY, I WOULD STERNLY
DON'T BEAR SENATOR HAGEL ANY
ILL WILL PERSONALLY.
HE SUPPORTED BOTH OF MY
NOMINATIONS IN THE BUSH
ADMINISTRATION.
HE GAVE ME A LOT OF GOOD
ADVICE AND HELPED OUT BEHIND
THE SCENES.
SO I'M CERTAINLY PERSONALLY
GRATEFUL TO HIM FOR ALL OF
THAT AND WHAT IS INTERESTING
THIS CONTROVERSY APPEARS TO
BE STARTING PRIMARILY AMONG
DEMOCRATS.
JEWISH DEMOCRATS, WHO ARE
WORRIED ABOUT THIS POTENTIAL
NOMINATION.
MEGYN: WHAT SPECIFICALLY HAS
CHUCK HAGEL DONE?
HE IS A REPUBLICAN IN THE
SENATE FOR 12 YEARS.
HE WAS A MORE MODERATE
REPUBLICAN, THAT REAL
STAUNCH CONSERVATIVES NEVER
MUCH LIKED HIM BECAUSE HE
DIDN'T SORT OF VOTE ALONG
THE PARTY LINE BUT WHAT
SPECIFICALLY ON ISRAEL HAS
HE SAID OR DONE THAT HASD ABOUT?
>> AS I SAY HE VOTED ALONG
PARTY LINES THAT I'M
CERTAINLY GRATEFUL FOR.
MEGYN: I SEE YOUR STANDARD.
THIS IS GOOD TO KNOW ABOUT
YOU.
WE HAVE TO CHECK THE RECORD
TO SEE IF THE LAWMAKERS
VOTED FOR YOU.
>> JUST WANTED TO GET THAT
OUT THERE.
IN 2007, THE HARDEST VOTE I
THINK TO EXPLAIN IS THAT HE
DECLINED TO VOTE THE IRANIAN
REVOLUTIONARY GUARDS CORPS
AS A FOREIGN TERRORIST
ORGANIZATION.
THAT WAS THE VERY TIME THE
IRGC WAS ARMING AND EQUIPING
SHIITE TERRORISTS IN IRAQ
WHO WERE ATTACKING AMERICAN
AND OTHER COALITION FORCES
WHEN IRGC PEOPLE WERE
TRAINING AND ARMING AND
FINANCING HEZBOLLAH IN
LEBANON, AND THE LIST GOES
ON AND ON.
SO I THINK THIS IS, PEOPLE
ARE GOING TO HAVE A LOT OF
QUESTIONS ABOUT WHAT THAT
MEANS FOR THE ENTIRE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION POLICY.
AND I THINK, THE FACT THAT
SO MUCH OF THIS OPPOSITION,
THESE QUESTIONS, THAT ARE
BEING RAISED, COME FROM
STRONG DEMOCRATIC PARTY
SUPPORTERS MAY WELL THROW A
WRENCH INTO THE WHITE HOUSE
PLANS TO HAVE A PACKAGE
ANNOUNCEMENT OF THE NEW
NATIONAL SECURITY TEAM IN
THE NEXT FEW DAYS.
MEGYN: COULD THIS BE, COULD
THIS BE A DEAL BREAKER?
COULD HE ACTUALLY NOT GET
THE NECESSARY SUPPORT?
>> WELL, I THINK IT'S TOO
EARLY TO SAY THAT.
ALTHOUGH, I'M VERY SURPRISED
AT THE LEVEL OF, OF
OPPOSITION ALREADY BEING
VOICED.
AND A LOT DEPENDS HOW
REPUBLICANS INCLUDING
SENATOR McCAIN, DECIDE
THEY'RE GOING TO GO.
YOU KNOW, HE AND SENATOR
HAGEL WERE BOTH VIETNAM
VETERANS.
THEY WERE CLOSE IN THE
SENATE.
AND YET, SENATOR HAGEL
ENDORSED PRESIDENT OBAMA IN
2008.
HE DID NOT ENDORSE SENATOR
McCAIN.
I DON'T, BELIEVE ME, I DON'T
THINK SENATOR McCAIN WOULD
REACT OUT OF PERSONAL PIQUE.
I DON'T THINK THAT DROVE HIS
CONCERN ABOUT SUSAN RICE AND
I DON'T THINK IT WOULD DRIVE
THE POSITION ON CHUCK HAGEL.
A LOT OF REPUBLICANS LOOK TO
SENATOR McCAIN, IF THE
NOMINATION OCCURS, WE'RE IN
THE PHASE TALKING ABOUT
NOMINATIONS THAT HAVEN'T
OCCURRED AGAIN, BUT IF IT
WERE TO OCCUR I THINK
SENATOR McCAIN'S POSITION
COULD BE PIVOTAL.
MEGYN: QUICKLY BEFORE I LET
YOU GO I DIDN'T HEAR YOUR
REACTION TO SUSAN RICE
OFFICIALLY OUT AS POSSIBLE
NEXT SECRETARY OF STATE?
>> IT IS A GREAT PERSONAL
DISAPPOINTMENT FOR HER AND
WHEN YOU GO INTO MEETINGS
WITH SENATORS AND COME OUT
WITH THEM HAVING MORE
QUESTIONS THAN WHEN YOU WENT
IN IT'S A REAL PROBLEM IN A
CONFIRMATION PROCESS.
I THINK THE PRESIDENT
DECIDED IT WASN'T WORTH THE
POLITICAL COST TO HIM.
HE HAS 55 DEMOCRATS IN THE
SENATE.
IF HE HAD REALLY WANTED TO
PUSH IT THROUGH I THINK HE
WOULD HAVE SUCCEEDED.
SO THE CALCULUS WAS THE
PRESIDENT'S TO MAKE IT
WASN'T POLITICALLY WORTH IT.
MEGYN: THAT IS WIDELY
BELIEVED SENATOR KERRY WILL
ASSEND TO THAT POSITION.
AMBASSADOR BOLTON, THANKS
FOR BEING HERE.
>> THANK YOU.
MEGYN: IN THE AFTERMATH OF
THE TRAGEDY AT NEWTOWN'S
FRIENDS OF THE GUNMAN'S
MOTHER ARE TELLING THE WORLD
ABOUT THE CHALLENGES SHE
FACED WITH HER SON.
UP NEXT THAT POWERFUL
INTERVIEW ALONG WITH A PANEL
OF PARENTS AND DOCTORS IN
ONE OF THE MOST IMPORTANT
CONVERSATIONS OF THE DAY.
>> YOU SAID THAT THERE WERE
DIFFERENT THINGS THAT SHE
TRIED TO DO BECAUSE SHE HAD
HARD TIME BONDING WITH HIM?
>> YEAH.
SHE WAS TRYING TO BOND, FIND
WAYS TO BOND WITH HIM AND
YOU KNOW, SHE TOLD ME THE
GUNS, YOU KNOW, SHE WOULD
TAKE THEM SHOOTING BECAUSE
THAT WAS A WAY THAT, YOU
KNOW A SINGLE MOM COULD, YOU
KNOW, RELATE TO HER SON.
AND, SO SHE WOULD TAKE HIM,
TAKE HIM OUT SHOOTING
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
MEGYN: WELL, IN THE AFTERMATH OF
THE TRAGEDY AT NEWTOWN, FRIENDS
OF THE GUNMAN'S MOTHER, NANCY
LANZA, ARE TELLING THE WORLD
ABOUT THE CHALLENGES SHE SAYS
SHE FACED RAISING HER SON, AND
ONE IS OPENING UP ABOUT THE
COMMON POND THAT BROUGHT THIS
MAN -- COMMON BOND THAT BROUGHT
THIS MAN AND LANZA TOGETHER AS
FRIENDS.
>> Reporter: AND WHAT KIND OF
THINGS DID SHE TELL YOU ABOUT
HER SON?
>> NANCY WOULD GET UPSET BECAUSE
HER SON REFUSED TO LET HER TOUCH
HIM.
YOU KNOW, SHE COULDN'T HUG HIM.
WHERE MY SON'S JUST THE
OPPOSITE, YOU KNOW SHE'D SEE MY
SON HANGING ALL OVER ME.
BUT, YOU KNOW, AUTISTIC KIDS,
EACH AND EVERY ONE OF THEM IS
DIFFERENT.
>> Reporter: AND YOU SAID THAT
THERE WERE DIFFERENT THINGS THAT
SHE TRIED TO DO BECAUSE SHE HAD
A HARD TIME BONDING WITH HIM.
>> YEAH.
SHE WAS TRYING TO BOND, FIND
WAYS TO BOND WITH HIM, AND, YOU
KNOW, SHE TOLD ME THE GUNS, YOU
KNOW, SHE WOULD TAKE THEM
SHOOTING BECAUSE THAT WAS A WAY
THAT, YOU KNOW, A SINGLE MOM
COULD, YOU KNOW, RELATE TO HER
SON.
AND SO SHE WOULD TAKE HIM, TAKE
HIM OUT SHOOTING.
>> Reporter: AND WAS THAT
SOMETHING THAT THEY DID MULTIPLE
TIMES, WAS THAT SOMETHING THAT
SHE FOUND WAS AN EASY WAY FOR
THEM TO BOND TOGETHER?
OR WAS IT SOMETHING THAT SHE
JUST TRIED?
>> I THINK IT WAS RELATIVELY
NEW.
BUT, YOU KNOW, IT'S SOMETHING
THAT I THINK HE ENJOYED, AND SO,
YOU KNOW, SHE USED THE
OPPORTUNITY TO DO IT WITH HIM,
YOU KNOW?
SO THAT SHE COULD HAVE SOME
QUALITY TIME WITH HER SON.
MEGYN: JOINING ME NOW, DIRECTOR
OF COMMUNICATIONS FOR THE
ELIZABETH BERG CENTER FOR LAW
AND ADVOCACY.
AND JOHN GILMOUR IS THE DIRECT
OF THE AUTISM NETWORK.
MICHAEL JOHN CARLY IS THE
EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF THE GLOBAL
AND REGIONAL ASPERGER'S
SYNDROME, AND DR. ROBERT MALILLO
IS THE CO-FOUNDER OF BRAIN
BALANCE CENTERS WHICH LOOKS AT
ALL DISORDERS ON THE AUTISM
SPECTRUM AND BEYOND.
THANK YOU ALL SO MUCH FOR BEING
HERE.
>> WHERE YOU'RE WELCOME.
MEGYN: APPRECIATE IT.
LET ME START WITH YOU, REBECCA.
>> SURE.
MEGYN: THERE WAS A PIECE POSTED
ONLINE, I KNOW YOU HAVEN'T
LOOKED AT THIS, BUT IT'S CALLED
I AM ADAM LANZA'S MOTHER, AND
IT'S WRITTEN BY A WOMAN -- IT'S
NOT, OBVIOUSLY, HIS MOTHER, BUT
SHE TALKS ABOUT HOW SHE HAS A
SON WHO TERRIFIES HER.
AUTISM SPECTRUM, ADHD, OPTIONAL
DEFINAL, EXPLOSIVE DISORDER.
SHE BASICALLY SAYS SHE'S AFRAID
OF HER SON.
THEY DON'T KNOW EXACTLY WHAT'S
WRONG WITH HIM, BUT SHE DOESN'T
FEEL THERE IS A PLACE RIGHT NOW
IN SOCIETY TO GET THE RIGHT
HELP.
>> THE SERVICES.
MEGYN: THE SERVICES.
YOUR THOUGHTS.
>> MY THOUGHTS ARE THERE ARE SO
MANY COMORBID SITUATIONS IN SOME
OF THESE KIDS WITH AUTISM --
MEGYN: WHAT DO YOU MEAN BY THAT,
COMORBID?
>> COMORBID MEANS YOU COULD HAVE
ADHD, YOU CAN HAVE OPPOSITIONAL
DEFIANCE DISORDER.
I COULD NOT HAVE WRITTEN THAT
ARTICLE BECAUSE MY SON IS NOT,
DOES NOT HAVE MELTDOWNS AND IS
NOT VIOLENT, BUT MY SON PROBABLY
COULD HAVE, WELL, WE WERE ABLE
TO ACCESS THE RIGHT SERVICES
VERY YOUNG, AND HE GOT THOSE
IMPULSES UNDER CONTROL.
AND WHAT WE DON'T KNOW RIGHT NOW
IS ENOUGH INFORMATION ABOUT WHAT
ADAM, WHAT WAS GOING ON, HOW
MANY SERVICES.
WE DON'T EVEN KNOW TRULY WHAT
HIS CORRECT DIAGNOSE KNOW CEASE
IS.
MEGYN: AND I WANT TO EMPHASIZE
THAT WE'RE TALKING ABOUT THIS AT
ALL BECAUSE THE BROTHER, RYAN
LANZA, REPORTEDLY TOLD THE
POLICE THAT HIS BROTHER SUFFERED
FROM -- WAS ON THE AUTISM
SPECTRUM, AND HE REPORTEDLY USED
THE WORD AS ASPERGER'S WHICH IS
SORT OF CONSIDERED ON THE AUTISM
SPECTRUM BUT MAYBE NOT FOR MUCH
LONGER.
IN ANY EVENT, SO MANY PEOPLE,
DOCTOR, SOMETHING OVER 1.5
MILLION HAVE ASPERGER'S OR HAVE
AUTISM IN THIS COUNTRY.
>> UH-HUH.
MEGYN: 99 PERCENT OF THEM COMMIT
NO VIOLENT CRIME.
SHOULD WE EVEN BE TALKING ABOUT
THIS?
>> YES, I THINK WE SHOULD
BECAUSE, ONE, I THINK WE'VE
IGNORED THESE PROBLEMS FOR TOO
LONG.
ALTHOUGH THIS IS AN UNFORTUNATE
SITUATION, IT'S BRINGING UP A
GOOD OPPORTUNITY TO TALK ABOUT
SOMETHING THAT I THINK HAS BEEN
IGNORED BY THIS COUNTRY FOR WAY
TOO LONG.
WE'VE BEEN SPENDING SO MUCH TIME
TALKING ABOUT POLITICS AND THE
ECONOMY, AND WE'VE FORGOTTEN
ABOUT OUR CHILDREN.
WE'RE LITERALLY SEEING AN
EPIDEMIC OF THESE ISSUES RIGHT
NOW.
THESE ARE NEUROLOGICAL
PROBLEMS --
MEGYN: THESE ARE NOT MENTAL
ILLNESSESES, RIGHT?
>> NO.
IT'S A NEUROLOGICAL PROBLEM.
AND IN MANY WAYS, YOU KNOW, IT
CAN BE PREVENTED, IT CAN BE
TREATED EFFECTIVELY.
BUT MOST KIDS I DON'T THINK ARE
GETTING THE PROPER RESOURCES
THAT THEY NEED.
AND I THINK THAT, YOU KNOW, IT'S
POSSIBLE TO CONCEIVE OF THAT
THIS COULD HAVE BEEN PREVENTED.
MEGYN: JOHN GILMOUR, THEY SAID
THIS MOM, NANCY, DECIDED TO HOME
SCHOOL HIM FOR SOME PERIOD OF
TIME BECAUSE SHE DIDN'T FEEL
LIKE SHE WAS GETTING THE SUPPORT
SHE NEEDED UNLIKE REBECCA.
IT, OBVIOUSLY, SHE WAS NOT AS
SUPPORTED AS SHE NEEDED TO BE.
THAT SEEMS TO BE CLEAR TO US.
WHAT ARE YOUR THOUGHTS?
>> WELL, IT'S ACTUALLY NOT
UNUSUAL FOR PEOPLE WHO HAVE
CHILDREN ON AUTISM SPECTRUM TO
HOME SCHOOL THEM.
MANY PUBLIC SCHOOLS AREN'T
REALLY EQUIPPED TO PROVIDE
APPROPRIATE SETTING OR EDUCATION
FOR CHILDREN WITH AUTISM.
BUT IT SEEMS LIKE, YOU KNOW,
WITH THIS CASE WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT A YOUNG MAN, AND WHEN THEY
GET TO THEIR 20s, THERE'S A
COMPLETE EVAPORATION OF
SERVICES.
MEGYN: RIGHT.
BECAUSE THEY'VE GONE THROUGH THE
SCHOOL SYSTEM FOR ALL THOSE
YEARS, AND THERE'S BEEN SUPPORT,
AND THEN SUDDENLY IT'S GONE.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
WE TALK ABOUT IT IN OUR
COMMUNITY AS THE DAY THE BUS
STOPS SHOWING UP.
MEGYN: AND WHAT'S THE GENERAL
CONSENSUS ON THAT?
>> WELL, A LOT OF FEAR AND, YOU
KNOW, AT LEAST FOR SOME OF US
WHAT WE'RE TRYING TO DO AS MUCH
AS WE CAN TO SORT OF IMPROVE THE
SITUATION.
YOU KNOW, ONE THING STRUCK ME
ABOUT THIS, THOUGH, IS THAT I
THINK IT KIND OF
MISCHARACTERIZES PEOPLE ON THE
AUTISTIC SPECTRUM -- IF HE
WAS --
MEGYN: RIGHT.
UNCONFIRMED STILL.
>> RIGHT.
ANOTHER UNCONFIRMED REPORT WAS
THAT HE WAS TAKING A VERY
POWERFUL ANTIPSYCHOTIC DRUG.
NOW, THAT WOULD SEEM TO
INDICATE -- WHICH IS NOT
RECOMMENDED FOR AUTISM OR
ASPERGER'S.
SO THAT WOULD SEEM TO INDICATE
THERE'S OTHER ISSUES GOING ON
WITH THIS YOUNG MAN BEFORE THIS
HAPPENED.
MEGYN: MICHAEL JOHN, YOUR
THOUGHTS ON THE REPORTS OF THE
GUNS BEING IN THE HOME.
I DON'T WANT TO MAKE THIS A GUN
DISCUSSION, BUT THE MOTHER WAS A
GUN ENTHUSIAST WHICH, YOU KNOW,
THAT'S LEGAL IN THIS COUNTRY,
BUT IS THERE HEIGHTENED CONCERN
FOR KEEPING THAT KIND OF WEAPON
IN THE HOUSE IN YOUR VIEW WITH A
CHILD THAT'S ON THE AUTISM
SPECTRUM, OR, FORGET THAT, HAS
JUST HAD THESE TYPE OF MENTAL
ISSUES IN THEIR PAST?
>> ARE WELL, JUST FOCUSING ON
THE AUTISM SPECTRUM ASPECT OF
IT, I WOULD SAY, NO, IT'S NOT
NECESSARILY GOING TO PLAY A ROLE
IN WHETHER OR NOT THE CHILD IS
GOING THE USE THOSE GUNS
NECESSARILY.
FOLKS ON THE SPECTRUM SUCH AS
MYSELF, SUCH AS MY SON, SUCH AS
G.R.A.S.S. MEMBERS, WE DON'T
LIKE AMBIGUITY TOO MUCH, WE
DON'T LIKE, YOU KNOW,
UNCERTAINTY IN LIFE.
THE WORLD IS CONFUSING ENOUGH
SOMETIMES.
SO RULES AND REGULATIONS,
THEY'RE KIND OF LIKE SAFETY
VALVES, YOU KNOW?
WE APPRECIATE THEM BECAUSE THEN
EVERYTHING IS CLEAR.
SO, YOU KNOW, USUALLY ON THE
SPECTRUM YOU'RE GOING TO SEE
MORE OF A PREPONDERANCE FOR AN
INDIVIDUAL OBEYING THE LAW MAYBE
A LITTLE BIT TOO MUCH RATHER
THAN DISOBEYING THE LAW.
MEGYN: DOCTOR, WHAT ARE THE
OPTIONS FOR A MOTHER LIKE THIS
WHO, YOU KNOW, WHATEVER HIS
ISSUE WAS, YOU KNOW, EXTREMELY
WITHDRAWN, EXTREMELY INTELLIGENT
BUT GROWING MORE AND MORE
TROUBLED IN RECENT YEARS
ACCORDING TO THE REPORTS, ALL OF
WHICH REMAINS CONFIRMED, BUT WE
NEED TO GET THIS OUT THERE
BECAUSE ALREADY THE DISCUSSION
ABOUT THESE THINGS IS OUT THERE,
WHAT ARE THE OPTIONS FOR SUCH A
MOTHER?
>> YEAH.
THERE ARE OPTIONS OUT THERE
OTHER THAN JUST THROWING
MEDICATION AT KIDS WHICH REALLY,
AGAIN, MAY OR MAY NOT BE
APPROPRIATE.
BUT IT'S NOT THE LONG-TERM
ANSWER, WE FOE THAT.
THERE ARE -- WE KNOW THAT.
WE HAVE BRAIN BALANCE CENTERS
WHICH ARE OUT THERE --
MEGYN: WHERE YOU CAN HAVE YOUR
CHILD TESTED AND GET A
MEANINGFUL DIAGNOSIS BACK?
>> WHERE WE CAN WORK WITH THE
PROBLEM.
IT'S NOT ABOUT LABELING, BECAUSE
EVERYBODY IS DIFFERENT, EVERY
CHILD IS DIFFERENT.
THEY MAY FOLLOW THE RULES, BUT
THEN THERE MAY BE OTHERS THAT
HAVE NO EMPATHY, THAT REALLY
DON'T FEEL MUCH IN THE WAY OF
PAIN OR COMPASSION AND MAY BE
PRONE TO ANGER AND OUTBURST, SO
THERE ARE ALL DIFFERENT TYPES.
THE UNDERLYING PROBLEM IS THE
SAME.
THERE ARE NEUROLOGICAL
IMBALANCES, AND WE CAN DEAL WITH
THESE WITH MULTIMODAL
TREATMENTS, DIFFERENT
THERAPISTS, PHYSICAL THERAPY,
BEHAVIORAL THERAPY, NUTRITION.
ALL OF THAT IS VERY, VERY
IMPORTANT.
THERE'S A LOT OF OPTIONS OUT
THERE.
MEGYN: AND YET OUTBURSTS, JUST
BECAUSE A CHILD HAS OUTBURSTS
WHO'S ON THE AUTISM SPECTRUM
DOESN'T MEAN ANYTHING ABOUT
WHETHER THEY'RE GOING TO BE
VIOLENT, THEY CAN HAVE
ASPERGER'S BECAUSE YOU TOOK A
STICK OF GUM, AND YOU DIDN'T
WANT THEM TO TAKE IT.
>> IF THEY'RE TRYING TO
COMMUNICATE SOMETHING AND YOU
DON'T KNOW HOW, IT'S GOING TO BE
PRESENT INSIDE A VERY DIFFERENT
WAY, AND THAT MAY BE REMITTED AS
A TANTRUM. -- REMITTED AS A
TANTRUM.
MEGYN: REBECCA, THE MESSAGE WE
NEED TO TAKE AWAY FROM THIS?
>> I FEEL HORRIBLE ABOUT THE
SITUATION, I THINK, UM, THE
REASON MY SON GOT THE SERVICES
HE NEEDED WAS BECAUSE I WAS
TENACIOUS.
MY HUSBAND AND I HIRED AN
ATTORNEY TO MAKE SURE HE GOT THE
SERVICES HE NEEDED.
I KNOW THAT MOST OF THE PARENTS
OUT THERE CAN'T DO THAT, BUT
THEY CAN LOOK INTO FREE
ADVOCATES AND JUST TO NOT STOP.
GET EVERY SINGLE THING YOU CAN
FOR YOUR CHILDREN TO MAKE SURE
THAT THINGS LIKE THIS NEVER
HAPPEN IN THE FUTURE.
MEGYN: GOT TO BE A MOTHER
WARRIOR OR A FATHER WARRIOR.
THANK YOU ALL.
WE'LL POST MORE ON OUR WEB SITE,
FOXNEWS.COM.brea
THERE
So now I can be in
the scene.
ADVAIR is
clinically proven to help
significantly improve
lung function.
Unlike most COPD medications,
ADVAIR contains both an
anti-inflammatory
and a
long-acting bronchodilator
working together to help improve
your lung function all day.
ADVAIR won't
replace fast-acting inhalers
for sudden symptoms
and should not be used more
than twice a day.
People with
COPD taking ADVAIR
may have a higher chance
of pneumonia.
ADVAIR may increase your
risk of osteoporosis
and some eye problems.
Tell your doctor
if you have a heart condition
or high blood pressure before
taking ADVAIR.
If you're still
having difficulty breathing,
ask your doctor if including
ADVAIR could help
improve your lung function.
Get your
first full
prescription
free
and save
on refills
at
ADVAIRcopd.com.
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAN
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
MEGYN: KELLY'S COURT IS BACK IN
SESSION, ON THE DOCKET TODAY,
THE CONNECTICUT GUNMAN'S MOTHER,
NANCY, WAS REPORTEDLY A BIG GUN
ENTHUSIAST AND HAD ALL OF THESE
WEAPONS IN HER HOUSE REGISTERED
AND SO ON.
BUT DID SHE BREAK ANY LAWS
HAVING SOMEONE IN HER HOME WITH
SOME SORT OF MENTAL DISORDER, IT
APPEARS, AND ALL OF THOSE
WEAPONS?
JOINING ME NOW TO DISCUSS IT,
LIS WIEHL, FOX NEWS LEGAL
ANALYST, AND MARK EIGLARSH,
FORMER PROSECUTOR AND DEFENSE
ATTORNEY.
SO THIS ISN'T A GUN DEBATE PER
SE, BUT IT'S A DEBATE ABOUT WHAT
A LOT OF FOLKS ARE TALKING
ABOUT, YOU KNOW, SHOULD THE LAWS
BE STRICTER AND SO ON, AND THE
QUESTION IS, HOW STRICT ARE THE
LAWS IN CONNECTICUT, AND DID SHE
BREAK ANY OF THEM WITH THESE
GUNS?
>> THE LAWS ARE NOT STRICT IN
CONNECTICUT, AND EVEN IF SHE
TOOK -- THE MOTHER -- EVEN IF
SHE TOOK HER SON, AN UNLICENSED
GUN OWNER, TO A SHOOTING RANGE,
THERE HAVE BEEN SOME REPORTS SHE
MAY HAVE LET HIM SHOOT, EVEN IF
SHE DID ALL OF THOSE THINGS,
MEGYN, THAT'S PERFECTLY LEGAL
UNDER CONNECTICUT LAW TO TAKE
SOMEONE WHO DOESN'T HAVE A
LICENSE AND LET THEM SHOOT AT A
RANGE.
MEGYN: MARK, WHEN I READ UP
ABOUT THIS, THEY SAID THAT
CONNECTICUT'S GUN LAWS ARE THE
FOURTH MOST STRICT IN THE
COUNTRY.
>> YEAH.
LIS IS ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
IF WE'RE ANALYZING HER SPECIFIC
BEHAVIOR, WE TRACE FIRST HER
CHOICE TO LET HER SON SHOOT
WEAPONS WITH HER, AND LIS IS
ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
AS LONG AS SHE IMMEDIATELY
SUPERVISED AN UNLICENSED GUN
HANDLER, SHE'S ALLOWED TO DO
THAT.
MEGYN: OKAY, BUT WAIT.
BEFORE WE GET TO THAT, HOLD ON,
HOLD ON, BEFORE WE GET TO THAT,
SHE OWNED ALL THE GUNS LEGALLY,
CORRECT?
>> CORRECT.
MEGYN: OKAY.
AND SHE JUMPED THROUGH ALL THE
HOOPS SHE NEEDED TO.
SHE DID ALL THAT, SHE PASSED ALL
THAT, SHE HAD THESE WEAPONS
LEGALLY.
>> YES.
MEGYN: OKAY.
BUT NOW WE'RE MOVING ON TO THE
QUESTION ABOUT WHETHER THERE'S
ANY RESTRICTION ON HAVING SUCH A
GUN IF YOU HAVE SOMEBODY IN YOUR
HOUSE LIKE THIS SON WHO,
WHOSE -- WE DON'T KNOW EXACTLY
WHAT HE WAS SUFFERING FROM, LIS.
>> WELL, THAT'S THE PROBLEM, WE
DON'T HAVE A DIAGNOSIS YET.
LET ME PUT IT THIS WAY, IF SHE
KNEW THAT HE WAS ABOUT TO COMMIT
AN ACT OF VIOLENCE, IF THERE'S
SOMETHING ON THE COMPUTERRER --
WE'LL NEVER KNOW, EXAIVEL, WHAT
THEIR CONVERSATION WAS, BUT IF
THERE WAS SOMETHING ON ON THE
COMPUTER, IF THERE WERE NOTES OR
SOMETHING LIKE THAT WHERE SHE
HAD CAUSE TO BELIEVE HE WAS
GOING TO GO OUT AND SHOOT UP
THAT SCHOOL, THEN THERE'S AN
ISSUE THERE.
BUT JUST THE FACT THE KID HAS
SOME MENTAL PROBLEMS AND SHE'S
GOT THE GUNS LEGALLY, THE MOST
YOU COULD GO FOR IS CHILD
ENDANGERMENT, HER CHILD.
MEGYN: IT LOOKS LIKE, OBVIOUSLY,
THE MOTHER IS DECEASED, SO THIS
IS A HYPOTHETICAL QUESTION ABOUT
WHAT THE OBLIGATIONS ARE OF
WHETHER OR
PARENTS WHO HAVE CHILDREN IN
THEIR HOME WITH MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES.
POSSESSION OF A FIREARM IS
REGULATED BOTH BY FEDERAL LAW
AND THAT OF 45 STATES, BUT IT
ONLY APPLIES TO THE PERSON
APPLYING.
SO YOU CAN HAVE SOMEBODY IN YOUR
HOUSE THEN IN ALMOST ALL STATES
WHO IS, WHO'S BEEN DIAGNOSED AS
MENTALLY ILL, WHO MAY BE A
SCHIZOPHRENIC, AND YOU CAN HAVE
A GUN IN THE HOUSE?
>> YES.
THERE'S NO EVIDENCE TO SUGGEST
THAT HE EVER HAD ANY OF THOSE
WEAPONS IN HIS HANDS WITHOUT HER
SUPERVISION AT A GUN RANGE, AND
SO MERELY SAYING THAT SOMEBODY
HAS MENTAL ILLNESSES DOESN'T
NECESSARILY MEAN THAT IT'S
REASONABLY FORESEEABLE THAT
THEY'RE GOING TO GAIN ACCESS TO
GUNS AND THEN GO OUT AND DO THIS
HORRIFIC ACT.
>> AND THAT'S, THAT'S WHAT WE
NEED TO FIND OUT, MEGYN, IN THE
ENSUING DAYS, FIND OUT WHAT DID
SHE KNOW AND WHEN.
COMPUTERS, NOTES --
>> IT'S GOING TO BE HARD TO DO
NOW.
>> WELL, I KNOW, BUT MARK'S
EXACTLY RIGHT, IS IT LEGAL?
YES.
MEGYN: YEAH.
AND IT'S NOT ILLEGAL FOR
SOMEBODY WITH AS ASPERGER'S TO
BE IN A HOME WITH GUNS.
>> WE CAN'T PUT LABELS ON PEOPLE
WITH MENTAL ILLNESSES.
MEGYN: YEAH.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
up
and it's so rich
and creamy...
is it really 100 calories?
Let me put you on webcan...
...lean roasted chicken...
and a creamy broth
Mmm
I can still see you.
[ Male announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
♪
MEGYN: WELL, PRESIDENT OBAMA
TRAVELED TO NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, ON SUNDAY IN HIS
ROLE AS COMFORTER IN CHIEF.
AND THAT'S A ROLE HE'S ASSUMED
AT LEAST FOUR TIMES NOW IN THE
WAKE OF MASS SHOOTINGS.
MR. OBAMA MEETING PRIVATELY WITH
THE VICTIMS' FAMILIES BEFORE
SPEAKING AT AN INNER FAITH
VIGIL, EXPRESSING SORROW FOR THE
20 CHILDREN WHOSE LIVES WERE
TAKEN FAR TOO SOON.
HERE ARE JUST SOME OF THE
PICTURES.
LOOK AT THEM.
RELEASED SO FAR TO THE MEDIA.
GOSH, WHEN YOU SEE THEM ALL
TOGETHER LIKE THAT.
HERE'S PRESIDENT OBAMA WITH THE
SIBLINGS OF LITTLE EMILY PARKER,
ONE OF THE VICTIMS.
EMILY'S FATHER, ROBBIE, FOUND
THE STRENGTH CAN -- INCREDIBLY O
OFFER WORDS OF SYMPATHY FOR THE
GUNMAN NOT LONG AFTER POLICE
RELEASED THE NAMES OF THE
VICTIMS.
AND HERE'S ANOTHER PHOTO OF THE
PRESIDENT WITH THE GRANDDAUGHTER
OF SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
PRINCIPAL DAWN WHO GAVE HER LIFE
CONFRONTING THE GUNMAN.
BOY, THEY JUST SAID THE NICEST
THINGS ABOUT THAT PRINCIPAL.
THEY SAID SHE WAS AMAZING, JUST
EXACTLY WHAT YOU'D WANT FOR AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL PRINCIPAL, AND
THEY HAD A PHILOSOPHY THERE OF
WORKING HARD AND BEING SMART AND
DOING WELL.
AND WHEN SHE GOT THERE AND SHE
ADDED THE MAXIM, HAVE FUN.
LAST NIGHT PRESIDENT OBAMA
OFFERED THESE WORDS:
>> I CAN ONLY HOPE IT HELPS FOR
YOU TO KNOW THAT YOU'RE NOT
ALONE IN YOUR GRIEF, THAT OUR
WORLD, TOO, HAS BEEN TORN APART,
THAT ALL ACROSS THIS LAND OF
OURS WE HAVE WEPT WITH YOU,
WE'VE PULLED OUR CHILDREN TIGHT.
AND YOU MUST KNOW THAT WHATEVER
MEASURE OF COMFORT WE CAN
PROVIDE, WE WILL PROVIDE.
WHATEVER PORTION OF SADNESS THAT
WE CAN SHARE WITH YOU TO EASE
THIS HEAVY LOAD, WE WILL GLADLY
BEAR IT.
MEGYN: WELL, THERE WAS ALSO AN
EMOTIONAL MOMENT JUST BEFORE THE
START OF LAST NIGHT'S VIGIL WHEN
THE COMMUNITY RECOGNIZED THE
FIRST RESPONDERS AS THEY ENTERED
THE AUDITORIUM FOR THEIR HEROIC
SERVICE IN THE AFTERMATH OF
THISCEPSLESS TRAGEDY.
WELL, WE ARE AWAITING REACTION
FROM CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR DAN
MALLOY WHO'S SCHEDULED TO
ADDRESS THIS TRAGEDY IN MOMENTS.
HE WAS THERE LAST NIGHT AS WELL
AND TALKED ABOUT THE STRENGTH OF
THAT COMMUNITY AND ALL THAI --
THEY'VE BEEN THROUGH, AND ALL OF
THE OFFICIALS LAST NIGHT
WELCOMING THE PRAYERS OF A
NATION THAT VERY MUCH HAVE
NEWTOWN IN THEIR HEARTS TODAY.
WE'LL BRING YOU THOSE COMMENTS,
STAY TUNED.