CHANNEL.
I'M JON SCOTT.
"SPECIAL REPORT" IS UP NEXT.
Captioned By
Closed Captioning Services, Inc
>> LET ME BEGIN EXPRESSING
GRATITUDE TO THE PEOPLE OF
NEWTOWN, PEOPLE OF
CONNECTICUT, PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES AND FRANKLY --
>> Bret: THIS IS A FOX NEWS
ALERT.
I'M BRET BAIER IN NEW YORK
TONIGHT.
LET'S TAKE YOU BACK TO
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WHERE
PRESS CONFERENCE HAS JUST
BEGUN.
THE CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR
MALLOY.
LISTEN IN.
>> CHILDREN, BEAUTIFUL,
BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN.
WHO HAD SIMPLY COME TO SCHOOL
TO LEARN.
>> THEIR DAY ENDED A DIFFERENT
WAY THAN WE COULD HAVE
IMAGINED.
AS WE STAND HERE TODAY WE
CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT TRANSPIRED
THERE.
EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY
TODAY.
IT'S TOO EARLY TO SPEAK OF
RECOVERY.
BUT EACH PARENT, EACH SIBLING,
EACH MEMBER OF THE FAMILY HAS
TO UNDERSTAND THAT
CONNECTICUT, WE'RE ALL IN THIS
TOGETHER.
WE'LL DO WHATEVER WE CAN TO
OVERCOME THIS EVENT.
WE WILL GET THROUGH IT.
BUT THIS IS A TERRIBLE TIME
FOR THIS COMMUNITY AND FOR
THESE FAMILIES.
OUR POLICE PERSONNEL AND
OTHERS ARE DOING THE UTMOST TO
CLEAR THIS SITUATION AS SOON
AS POSSIBLE.
TO RETURN THESE CHILDREN TO
THEIR PARENTS.
OR THESE LOVED ONES TO THEIR
FELLOW LOVED ONES AS QUICKLY
AS POSSIBLE.
WE'LL WORK WITH ALL OF THE
RESIDENTS OF THIS COMMUNITY.
AND CONNECTICUT TO MAKE SURE
THAT WE DO, IN FACT, GET
THROUGH THIS.
I WAS MAYOR OF STANFORD ON
9/11.
WHEN OUR STATE LOST MANY OF
ITS CITIZENS AND I LOST A
NUMBER OF MY FELLOW CITIZENS
AND FRIENDS.
I NEVER THOUGHT THAT IN A
PUBLIC CAREER THAT I WOULD
HAVE TO FACE THESE KIND OF
CIRCUMSTANCES OR THAT THEY
WOULD VISIT THEMSELVES UPON
THIS COMMUNITY OR THE PEOPLE
OF CONNECTICUT.
WE'LL GET THROUGH THIS.
AND OUR PRAYERS, AT THIS TIME
HAVE TO GO OUT TO THE
FAMILIES, SO AS I BEGAN BY
THANKING THOSE WITH EXPRESSED
THEIR DESIRES TO BE HELPFUL,
NUMBER ONE, WAY TO BE HELPFUL
IS TO SAY A PRAYER.
OR SEND A BEST WISH, THINKING
OF THE INDIVIDUALS WHO HAVE
SUFFERED SO MIGHTILY TODAY.
THANK YOU.
>> Bret: THAT IS CONNECTICUT
GOVERNOR DAN MALLOY WITH A
BRIEF STATEMENT THERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
OBVIOUSLY, EXPRESSING GRIEF
THERE.
AFTER THIS HORRIFIC DAY.
I'M BRET BAIER IN NEW YORK
TONIGHT.
WE BEGIN OUR COVERAGE FROM
NEWTOWN.
WE BEGIN WITH SENIOR
CORRESPONDENT RICK LEVENTHAL
WHO IS LIVE TONIGHT NEAR THE
SCHOOL.
HELLO, RICK.
>> Reporter: BRET, WE JUST
HEARD FROM THE GOVERNOR, FOR
THE SECOND TIME TODAY.
EXPRESSING HIS SORROW AND HIS
CONDOLENCES TO THE FAMILIES OF
ALL OF THOSE VICTIMS WHO
SUFFER TODAY AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN HANG
HANG, WHICH IS IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
AS WE NOW KNOW A YOUNG MAN
IDENTIFIED AS ADAM LANZA, 20
YEARS OLD, WENT IN TO THAT
SCHOOL THIS MORNING, OPENED
FIRE WITH APPARENTLY, WITH
THREE WEAPONS.
GLOCK HANDGUN, ANOTHER HANDGUN
AND SEMI-AUTOMATIC WEAPON AND
SLAUGHTERED 26 PEOPLE INSIDE
THAT SCHOOL BEFORE KILLING
HIMSELF.
WE HAVE NOW LEARNED THAT ADAM
LANZA LIVED WITH HIS MOTHER
HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
WOKE UP THIS MORNING,
ACCORDING TO THE FEDERAL
SOURCE, SHOT HIS MOTHER IN THE
FACE.
THEN TOOK HER CAR AND WENT TO
HER SCHOOL AND THAT IS WHERE
THIS HORRIBLE SHOOTING
TRANSPIRED.
HE KILLED 18 KIDS AT THE
SCHOOL.
TWO CHILDREN WERE FOUND THERE
AND MOVED TO A LOCAL HOSPITAL
WHERE THEY DIED.
SIX OTHER ADULTS BEFORE
KILLING HIMSELF.
WE KNOW THAT WHEN POLICE
ARRIVED ON SCENE JUST AFTER
9:30 THIS MORNING, THEY DIDN'T
WASTE ANY TIME.
THEY WENT INSIDE THE SCHOOL,
LOCATING ADULTS AND CHILDREN
AND MOVING THEM OUT OF THE
SCHOOL TO SAFETY, THAT IS THEN
WHEN THEY FOUND THE VICTIMS
ALL LOCATED WITHIN TWO ROOMS
OF THAT SCHOOL.
ONE AREA OF THAT SCHOOL.
SO AGAIN, HORRIFIC SET OF
CIRCUMSTANCES HERE.
WE NOW UNDERSTAND THAT THE
FATHER OF THE SHOOTER IS BEING
QUESTIONED IN NEW JERSEY BY
THE F.B.I.
THERE WERE EARLY REPORTS THAT
HE ALSO HAD BEEN KILLED.
THAT IS NOT THE CASE.
THE FATHER OF ADAM LANZA IS
BEING QUESTIONED BY FEDERAL
AUTHORITIES IN NEW JERSEY.
THE SHOOTER'S BROTHER RYAN
LANZA ALSO APPARENTLY
COOPERATING WITH AUTHORITIES
BEING QUESTIONED IN NEW
JERSEY.
THE SHOOTER ADAM MAY HAVE BEEN
CARRYING HIS BROTHER'S I.D.
WHICH LED TO EARLY CONFUSION
ABOUT WHO THE IDENTITY WAS.
THE SHOOTER ADAM LANZA, DEAD
AT THE SCENE.
SLAUGHTERED 26 PEOPLE INSIDE
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, BRET,
BEFORE KILLING HIMSELF.
AND NOW POLICE ARE GOING
THROUGH THE GRISLY TASK OF
PROCESSING THAT CRIME SCENE.
BRET?
>> Bret: RICK, THEY HAVE
BEEN TALKING ABOUT PROCESSING
THE CRIME SCENE.
YOU MENTIONED THAT AND DEALING
WITH THE FAMILIES.
AND THE BODIES TAKING THEM OUT
OF THERE.
WHAT ABOUT PROCESSING THAT
SCENE AND TRYING TO FIND OUT
WHAT WAS BEHIND THIS GUY AND
WHAT WAS HIS MOTIVE, WHAT
HAPPENED WITH THE BACKGROUND
OF THIS MAN?
FROM THE BEGINNING.
>> WELL, THAT KIND OF
INFORMATION, THE BEST
INFORMATION ABOUT THE MENTAL
CONDITION OF ADAM LANZA WILL
COME FROM HIS FATHER AND HIS
BROTHER, WHO ARE BEING
QUESTIONED BY THE FEDERAL
AUTHORITIES AT THIS TIME.
THERE MAY BE WRITINGS OR
COMPUTER POSTINGS THAT THEY
CAN LOCATE FROM HIS MOTHER'S
HOME.
HIS MOTHER, AS WE MENTIONED,
HAS BEEN KILLED.
BUT THE FATHER AND THE BROTHER
COULD PROVIDE INSIGHT, SOME
BACKGROUND TO WHAT THE
SHOOTER'S MOTIVES MAY HAVE
BEEN.
WE HAVE HEARD HE WAS MENTALLY
TROUBLED.
MAY HAVE BEEN LEARNING
DISABLED IN SOME WAY.
THAT ALSO IS SOMETHING THAT
THE AUTHORITIES WILL TRY TO
NAIL DOWN, AS THEY LOOK FOR
SOME KIND OF ANSWER HERE.
BUT THIS YOUNG MAN CLEARLY HAD
MAJOR ISSUE THIS MORNING WHEN
HE WOKE UP AND ACCORDING TO
FEDERAL AUTHORITIES KILLED HIS
MOTHER.
WENT TO HER SCHOOL AFTER SHE
WAS ALREADY DEAD.
KILLED EVERY KID IN HER CLASS.
>> Bret: AMAZING.
RICK LEVENTHAL LIVE OUTSIDE
THE SCHOOL.
RICK, THANK YOU.
FLAGS IN WASHINGTON, D.C.,
HAVE BEEN LOWERED TO HALF
IS THE FLAG AT THE
CAPITOL BUILDING AND WE'LL
TAKE A LOOK AT THE FLAG AT THE
WHITE HOUSE LOWERED TO HALF
STAFF TO REMEMBER THE VICTIMS
AND THE FAMILIES.
HERE TO GIVE US SOME
PERSPECTIVE ON THE SHOOTINGS,
RICH MARIONOS, THE ASSISTANT
DIRECTOR AND SPECIAL AGENT IN
CHARGE OF THE BUREAU OF
ALCOHOL, TOBACCO AND FIREARMS
AND EXPLOSIVES.
HE IS THE LEAD INVESTIGATOR
FOR CONTROL BUM LINE SHOOTINGS
IN 19 -- COLUMBINE SHOOTINGS
FROM 1999 AND JOINS US IN
WASHINGTON.
RICH, THANK U FOR BEING
HERE.
THIS IS A HORRIFIC
INVESTIGATION.
FIRST, IT'S TOUGH TO EVEN DEAL
WITH TO START THE
INVESTIGATION FOR EXPERTS WHO
HAVE BEEN TALKING ABOUT THIS
ALL DAY.
THEY SAID IT'S TOUGH TO EVEN
DO IT.
ONCE YOU GET IN TO IT, WHAT
ARE THEY DOING FROM THE
BEGINNING TO BEGIN THEIR
LOOKING IN TO THIS GUY AND
STARTING THE EVIDENTIARY
GATHERING?
>> Guest: I NEVER THOUGHT
ONCE AGAIN IN MY ENTIRE CAREER
I'D GO THROUGH ANOTHER
INCIDENT SIMILAR TO COLUMBINE.
THE ENTIRE BUREAU AND THE LAW
ENFORCEMENT MEMBERS ARE JUST
SADDENED AND SEND OUR
SYMPATHIES OUT TO THE
FAMILIES.
WE AS AN AGENCY WITH ATF AND
THE PARTNERS ARE SO COMMIT TO
MAKE SURE THAT WE COME UP WITH
A MOTIVE AND COME UP WITH
EVERY ANSWER TO TRY TO
ASCERTAIN HOW THIS EVENT
HAPPENED.
WHAT THEY WILL BE GOING THE
NEXT 24 HOURS WHICH IS
EXTREMELY IMPORTANT IS TO
IDENTIFY THE VICTIMS WITH THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER.
THEY WILL ALSO BE CONDUCTING
MANY TESTS, FORENSIC TESTS ON
THE WEAPONS, THE BALLISTICS
EVIDENCE, CHECKING THE
DIFFERENT LOCATIONS WHERE THE
OFFENDER, OR ANY OTHER
OFFENDERS MAY BE IN
ASSOCIATION WITH THIS GUY.
OCCUPIED OR ANYPLACE THEY MAY
SECRETED ANY ADDITIONAL
EVIDENCE.
THEY ARE GOING TO TRY TOTO
LOOK I'M SURE FROM THE LESSONS
LEARNED FROM THE VARIOUS
INVESTIGATIONS WE HAVE TAKEN
PART IN.
TO DO A FULL DATA MINE IN
SOCIAL MEDIA, TO FIND POSTINGS
TO LEAD TO MOTIVE, PHONE
RECORD, CREDIT CARD PURCHASES
TO DO A COMPLETE DIG-IN DATA
MINE TO ESTABLISH HOW SUCH A
SENSELESS TRAGEDY COULD HAPPEN
AGAIN IN UNITED STATES.
>> Bret: QUICKLY, HAS
ANYTHING CHANGED WITH SCHOOL
SECURITY?
THIS WAS AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
BUT HAS ANYTHING CHANGED
AROUND THE COUNTRY WITH SCHOOL
SECURITY SINCE COLUMBINE?
>> I THINK THE SCHOOL SECURITY
IN THE UNITED STATES HAS
GOTTEN MUCH, MUCH BETTER.
I THINK WE HAVE DONE A
TREMENDOUS JOB IN LAW
ENFORCEMENT, AND THROUGHOUT
THIS COUNTRY TO WORK ON PLANS
FOR ACTIVE SHOOTERS.
AS YOU COULD SEE THE
TREMENDOUS JOB THAT THE LAW
ENFORCEMENT COMMUNITY DID BY
GETTING IN THEIR QUICKLY AND
SWIFTLY AND SECURING THE
SAFETY.
THE OTHER MEMBERS OF THE
SCHOOL AND THE OTHER CHILDREN.
SCHOOL SAFETY WE DO A BETTER
JOB.
MANY SCHOOL SYSTEMS WE UTILIZE
ELECTRONIC IDENTIFICATION.
SIGNAGE SHEETS.
ONE ACCESS TO GET IN.
ONE ENTRY TO GET IN ONE EXIT
TO GET OUT.
WE HAVE COME A LONG WAY SINCE
COLUMBINE.
TO GET TO YOUR POINT, WE STILL
NEED TO IMPROVE.
PART OF IMPROVING IS FOR ALL
OF US IN THE LAW ENFORCEMENT
COMMUNITY TO TAKE THE LESSONS
LEARNED FROM ALL THE
SHOOTINGS, FROM VIRGINIA TECH,
COLUMBINE OR THIS AND PULL
RESOURCES TOGETHER TO COME UP
WITH SOLUTIONS BASED WORK TO
PROVIDE SCHOOL SYSTEM AND WORK
IN CONCERT WITH THEM TO MAKE
THE SCHOOLS THAT MUCH SAFER.
WE ARE ALSO A DEMOCRACY.
COUNTRY THAT IS BASED UPON
FREEDOM.
WE DON'T WANT TO LOCK DOWN OUR
SCHOOLS IN SOME FORM THAT
GIVES AWAY THAT FREEDOM.
>> Bret: RICH, ASSISTANT
DIRECTOR AND SPECIAL AGENT IN
CHARGE OF ATF.
RICH, THANK YOU SO MUCH BE.
BACK WITH YOU A LITTLE LATER.
STILL AHEAD, WHITE HOUSE
REACTION TO TODAY'S EVENTS.
AN EMOTIONAL REACTION AT THAT.
WE WILL CONTINUE OUR COVERAGE
OF THE DEADLY SCHOOL SHOOTING
IN CONNECTICUT.
KEEP IT HERE.
>> OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN
TODAY.
FOR THE PARENTS AND GRAND
PARENTS, SISTERS AND BROTHERS
OF THESE LITTLE CHILDREN.
AND THE FAMILIES OF THE ADULTS
THAT WERE LOST.
>> Bret: WELCOME BACK TO
"SPECIAL REPORT" ON A NIGHT OF
ALMOST UNIMAGINABLE SORROW FOR
PARENTS AND OTHERS IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, 65 MILES FROM US
HERE IN NEW YORK.
POLICE SAY A GUNMAN DRESSED IN
BLACK BODY ARMOR CAME IN TO
THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL THIS MORNING AND
STARTED OPENING FIRE.
WHEN IT WAS OVER, 27 WERE DEAD
AT THE SCHOOL.
SIX ADULTS, AND 20 CHILDREN.
ALONG WITH THE GUNMEN.
POLICE SAY ONE OTHER DOESN'T
WAS KILLED ELSEWHERE.
BELIEVED TO BE THE SHOOTER'S
MOTHER.
AN EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT OBAMA
SPOKE THIS AFTERNOON ABOUT THE
SHOOTINGS.
CHIEF WHITE HOUSE
CORRESPONDENT ED HENRY HAS
THAT PART OF THE STORY.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF FIVE AND TEN YEARS
OLD.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA STRUGGLING
TO KEEP HIS COMPOSURE, THE
GRIEF OF AN ENTIRE NATION
VISIBLE IN THE TEARS HE TRIED
AND FAILED TO SUPPRESS.
>> THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS.
>> EARLIER THE PRESIDENT SPOKE
TO CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR DAN
MALLOY, AS WELL AS F.B.I.
DIRECTOR ROBERT MUELLER WHO IS
COORDINATING THE INVESTIGATION
WITH STATE AUTHORITIES.
>> I OFFER GOVERNOR MALLOY BY
CONDOLENCES, ON BEHALF OF THE
NATION.
AND MADE IT CLEAR HE WILL HAVE
EVERY SINGLE RESOURCE THAT HE
NEEDS TO INVESTIGATE THIS
HEINOUS CRIME, CARE FOR THE
VICTIMS, COUNSEL THEIR
FAMILIES.
WE HAVE HAD TOO MANY TRAGEDIES
IN THE PAST FEW YEARS.
>> PARTISAN BICKERING SEEM
UNIMPORTANT.
DELIBERATIONS OF THE LOOMING
FISCAL CLIFF UNINTERRUPTED.
>> AT PL 10:30 THIS MORNING IN
THE OVAL OFFICE THE PRESIDENT
WAS NOTIFIED BY THE HOMELAND
SECURITY ADVISOR JOHN BRENNAN
OF THE SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
AT A SCHOOL.
THE PRESIDENT, RECEIVING
REGULAR UPDATES AS MORE
INFORMATION BECOMES AVAILABLE.
>> THE PRESIDENT HAS RECEIVED
MANY OF THOSE EMERGENCY
UPDATES OVER THE LAST FOUR
YEARS.
FROM A CONGRESSWOMAN SHOT AT A
SUPER MARKET IN TUCSON,
ARIZONA.
SHE SURVIVED BUT SIX OTHERS
DID NOT.
>> OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN BY
THE SUDDEN PASSING.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN.
>> TO AN AURORA COLORADO MOVIE
THEATER THIS PAST SUMMER.
>> 12 DEAD.
>> WHEN YOU HAVE AN
OPPORTUNITY TO VISIT WITH
FAMILIES WHO HAVE LOST THEIR
LOVED ONES AS I DESCRIBED TO
THEM, I COME TO THEM NOT SO
MUCH AS PRESIDENT, AS I DO AS
A FATHER.
AND AS A HUSBAND.
>> LATE THEY'RE SAME MONTH THE
PRESIDENT FACED CRITICISM FROM
LIBERALS FOR SPEECH TO THE
NATIONAL URBAN LEAGUE.
>> WHEN I SAID IN THE WAKE OF
TUCSON WAS WE WERE GOING TO
STAY ON THIS PERSISTENTLY.
>> THE WHERE HE TALKED ABOUT
VIOLENCE BUT CAREFULLY DANCED
AROUND THE ISSUE OF GUN
CONTROL AND OFFER NOD SPECIFIC
PLANS FOR FOLLOW-THROUGH.
>> WE IDENTIFY GUN OWNERSHIP
THAT PASS ON FROM GENERATION
TO GENERATION THAT HUNTING AND
SHOOTING ARE PART OF CHERISHED
NATIONAL HERITAGE BUT I ALSO
BELIEVE THAT A LOT OF GUN
OWNERS WOULD AGREE AK-47s
BELONG IN THE HANDS OF
SEASONALS NOT IN THE HANDS OF
CRIMINALS.
>> TODAY, DRAMATIC CHIEF.
SPECIFIC PROMISE OF ACTION IN
THE SECOND TERM.
>> THESE NEIGHBORHOODS ARE OUR
NEIGHBORHOODS.
THE CHILDREN ARE OUR CHILDREN.
>> WE HAVE TO COME TOGETHER TO
TAKE MEANINGFUL ACTION TO
PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE
THIS REGARDLESS OF POLITICS.
>> FOR NOW, THE PRESIDENT
ORDERED FLAGS BE FLOWN AT HALF
STAFF, MILITARY POSTS PUBLIC
BUILDINGS AND GROWN AND
INCLUDING THE WHITE HOUSE.
WHERE THERE IS A GRIEVING
STAFF AND FIRST FAMILY.
>> THIS EVENING, MICHELLE AND
I WILL DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY
PARENT IN AMERICA WILL DO,
WHICH IS HUG OUR CHILDREN
TIGHTER.
AND WE'LL TELL THEM THAT WE
LOVE THEM.
>> CAPTAIN MARK KELLY, HUSBAND
OF FORMER CONGRESSWOMAN
GABRIELLE GIFFORDS SAID TODAY
THAT SHE SENDS HER PRAYERS
FROM TUCSON, AND HE ADDED A
MEANINGFUL DISCUSSION OF THE
NATION'S GUN LAWS CAN NO
LONGER WAIT.
BRET?
>> Bret: ED HENRY LIVE ON
THE NORTH LAWN.
THANK YOU.
THIS WAS ONE OF THE WORST
SCHOOL SHOOTINGS IN AMERICAN
HISTORY.
WE WILL HAVE THE LATEST ON
HISTORIC AND TRAGIC SHOOTINGS
IN CONNECTICUT.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
>> THE CHILDREN OBVIOUSLY WERE
VERY SHAKEN.
THEY WERE CRYING IN THE
CLOSET, IN THE CLOSET OF THE
ART ROOM.
EVENTUALLY, THEY WERE LEAVING
AND WHEN THEY WERE LEAVING THE
POLICE MADE THEM HOLD HANDS,
THE POLICE TOLD THEM TO CLOSE
THEIR EYES.
♪
STOP! STOP! STOP!
COME BACK HERE!
HUMANS -- WE ARE BEAUTIFULLY
IMPERFECT CREATURES
LIVING IN
AN IMPERFECT WORLD.
THAT'S WHY LIBERTY MUTUAL
INSURANCE HAS YOUR BACK
WITH GREAT IDEAS
LIKE OUR OPTIONAL
BETTER CAR REPLACEMENT.
IF YOUR CAR IS TOTALED,
WE GIVE YOU THE MONEY
TO BUY ONE A MODEL YEAR NEWER.
CALL...
AND ASK ONE OF OUR INSURANCE
EXPERTS ABOUT IT TODAY.
HELLO?!
WE BELIEVE OUR CUSTOMERS
DO THEIR BEST
OUT THERE IN THE WORLD,
AND WE DO EVERYTHING WE CAN
TO BE THERE FOR THEM
WHEN THEY NEED US.
[Car alarm blaring]
CALL NOW AND ALSO ASK ABOUT
OUR 24/7 SUPPORT AND SERVICE.
CALL...
AND LOCK IN YOUR RATE
FOR 12 MONTHS TODAY.
LIBERTY MUTUAL INSURANCE.
RESPONSIBILITY.
WHAT'S YOUR POLICY?
>>> MOMENTS AGO, ERIC HOLDER
SPOKE OUT ABOUT THE SHOOTINGS.
>> AS A NATION, WE HAVE TO ASK
OURSELVES HARD QUESTIONS.
WE GATHER TOO OFTEN TO TALK
ABOUT THESE KIND OF INSTANCES.
WE NEED TO DISCUSS, WHO WE ARE
AS A NATION.
TALK ABOUT THE FREEDOMS THAT
WE HAVE, THE RIGHTS THAT WE
HAVE AND HOW THEY MIGHT BE
USED IN A RESPONSIBLE WAY.
>> Bret: THERE WILL BE A LOT
OF PEOPLE ANALYZING WHAT HE
SAID THERE.
MASS SHOOTINGS LIKE THIS HAVE
BECOME ALL TOO COMMON AND LIKE
THIS ONE, LIKE OTHERS, IT'S
SURE TO SPARK NEW ARGUMENTS ON
BOTH SIDES OF THE GUN CONTROL
ISSUE.
TONIGHT, CHIEF INTELLIGENCE
CORRESPONDENT CATHERINE
HERRIDGE LOOKS AT THE HISTORY
AND PARTICULARLY GRUESOME
YEAR.
>> YOU CAN NEVER BE PREPARED
FOR THIS TYPE OF INCIDENT.
WHAT HAS HAPPENED AND
TRANSPIRED WILL LEAVE A MARK
ON THIS COMMUNITY AND EVERY
FAMILY IMPACTED.
>> WHETHER IT'S THE SEARING
IMAGES FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, THE PANIC AT A
MALL IN PORTLAND, OREGON, ON
TUESDAY, WHEN TWO HOLIDAY
SHOPPERS WERE KILLED BY A
SINGLE SHOOTER OR MASS MURDER
AS SIKH TEMPLE IN WISCONSIN IN
AUGUST, THEY CAN'T BEGIN TO
EXPLAIN THE LOSS.
>> THE STATISTIC PROVIDE COLD
COMFORT FOR WHAT HAPPENED
TODAY.
IF YOU LOOK AT AN EVENT LIKE
TODAY YOU THINK WE HAVE GOT A
PROBLEM.
WE HAVE TO DO SOMETHING.
WHATEVER YOU DO, YOU NEED TO
MAKE SURE THAT IT'S SOMETHING
THAT, YOU KNOW, IS GOING TO BE
EFFECTIVE.
>> WHILE THE WORST SCHOOL
SHOOTING IN HISTORY REMAINS
VIRGINIA FECK IN 2007 WHERE 32
WERE GUNNED DOWN BAY STUDENT
THE RECENT CRIME DATED FROM
THE JUSTICE DEPARTMENT THAT
RUNS THROUGH 2008 SHOWS THAT
MULTIPLE VICTIM HOMICIDES IN
THIS COUNTRY ARE RARE.
WITH LESS THAN 1% OF THE
CRIMES INVOLVING FIVE OR MORE
VICTIMS.
>> GUN HOMICIDE BY INDIVIDUALS
IN THE LATE TEENS AND EARLY
20s LIKE THE VIRGINIA TECH
GUNMAN AND FRIDAY'S AED SHOOT
RER DOWN.
ACCORDING TO FEDERAL DATA, GUN
HOMICIDES BY PERSONS BETWEEN
18 AND 24 PEAKED AT 8600 IN
1993 AND DROPPED TO HALF THAT
BY 2008.
>> LAW ENFORCEMENT HAS BEEN
MAKING HERCULEAN EFFORTS TO
PREVENT THE TRAGEDY WE SAW
UNFOLD TODAY.
EFFORTS AT LAW ENFORCEMENT
DISPOSAL RANGE FROM GUN
BUY-BACK PROGRAM, BACKGROUND
CHECKS AND TART GETED EVIDENT
TO INTERDICT FLOW OF ILLEGAL
GUNS.
>> WHILE SCHOOLS AND
COMMUNITIES FAR FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT POSTED METORIALS
TO HONOR THE CHILDREN AND
FAMILIES THAT WILL NEVER SEE
ANOTHER BIRTHDAY, THE LAW
ENFORCEMENT SAYS THE IMPACT IS
AMPLIFIED IN AGE OF INSTANT
COMMUNICATION.
>> IT'S NOT THAT COMMON BUT
WHEN IT HAPPENS IT'S WIDELY
PUBLICIZED.
SCHOOLS TAKE ADDITIONAL
PRECAUTIONS AT THIS POINT IN
TIME TO PROTECT THEIR TEACHERS
AS WELL AS THE STUDENTS.
AND DOING DRILLS PERIODICALLY
DURING THE SCHOOL YEAR.
>> APRIL OF THIS YEAR, SEVEN
MAJOR SHOOTINGS IN THE
U.S. ALONE, ALL INVOLVED A
SINGLE SHOOTER WITH MULTIPLE
DEATHS.
WHAT IS NOT CLEAR TONIGHT IS
WHETHER THIS REPRESENTS ANYKINDE
NATIONAL STATISTICS LONG-TERM,
BRET?
>> Bret: THANK YOU.
>> YOU'RE WELCOME.
>> Bret: GO BACK OUT TO
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
CORRESPONDENT MOLLY LINE IS
OUTSIDE THE HOME OF A PERSON
BELIEVED TO BE THE SHOOTER'S
MOTHER WHO WAS KILLED BEFORE
THE SCHOOL MASSACRE.
HELLO, MOLLY.
>> Reporter: THIS IS WHERE
ADAM LANZA BELIEVED TO HAVE
WOKEN UP THIS MORNING AND SHOT
HIS MOTHER BEFORE TAKING HER
CAR AND HEADING TO THE SCHOOL.
DOING SOMETHING SO FAR FROM
WHAT THIS COMMUNITY WHAT BEEN
PREPARING FOR.
WE'RE IN A NEIGHBORHOOD FILLED
WITH CHRISTMAS LIGHTS.
NOW THIS COMMUNITY INSTEAD OF
PREPARING FOR ALL OF THAT JOY
WILL BE FACING DEEP SADNESS.
A STEADY STREAM OF POLICE
VEHICLES DRIVING IN THE USUAL
PEACEFUL NEW ENGLAND TOWN
SERVED AS A CONSTANT REMINDER
OF THE TRAGEDY THAT TRANSPIRED
HERE.
ANNA WAS WORKING IN HER CAFE
WHEN NEWS OF THE SHOOTING
BROKE.
THE PLACE FILLED WITH MOTHERS
GETTING MORNING COFFEE.
>> WE STARTED TO FREAK OUT NOT
KNOWING IF IT'S THE HIGH
SCHOOL, PEOPLE WERE CRYING NOT
KNOWING.
A COUPLE MINUTES LATER THEY
FOUND OUT IT WAS SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND I HAD A
CUSTOMER WITH TWO YOUNG
CHILDREN.
I THINK ONE KINDERGARTEN AGE
AND SHE WAS TOTALLY SCARED.
I READ IT ON HER FACE.
>> RESIDENTS WERE SHOCKED,
MOST NOT WANTING TO TALK.
THE EMOTION OF THE DAY EVIDENT
ON THEIR FACES.
THE SMALL CENTRAL VILLAGE AREA
FILLED WITH STORES THAT CATER
TO KIDS AND THE SIGN IN THE
WINDOW, OF A FUN CUT HAIR
SALON AND CONSIGNMENT SHOP
SAYS IT ALL.
INSIDE, THE OWNER WAS TRYING
TO COME TO GRIPS WITH THE LOSS
OF SO MANY CHILDREN.
>> I KNOW THE WHOLE TOWN,
PRACTICALLY.
I'M JUST WORRIED AND I'M SAD.
IT PUT MYSELF IN THEIR
POSITION.
IT'S TERRIBLE.
IT'S A SHOCKING THING, BECAUSE
YOU SEE THIS ON TV AND SOME
PLACE ELSE.
YOU DON'T THINK OF IT, AS
BEING HERE.
>> GRASS THE SADNESS THEY WILL
FACE IN COMING DAYS.
MORE THAN TWO DOZEN PEOPLE
WILL BE LAID TO REST, 20 OF
THEM CHILDREN.
>> Bret: WE DON'T STILL HAVE
THE NAMES OF THE VICTIMS,
RIGHT?
HAVE THEY BEEN ALL NOTIFIED?
>> AUTHORITIES ARE HOLDING
THOSE NAMES VERY CLOSE TO THE
VEST RIGHT NOW,
UNDERSTANDABLY.
THEY WANT TO GIVE THE PARENTS
OF THE CHILDREN AND ALSO OF
THE OTHER PEOPLE THAT WERE
KILLED FIRST KNOWLEDGE OF
THIS.
AND TIME TO PREPARE.
BRET?
>> Bret: OF COURSE, OF
COURSE.
BILL HEMMER -- THANK YOU,
MOLLY LINE, OUTSIDE THE HOME
OF THE MOTHER BELIEVED TO BE
KILLED THERE.
BILL HEMMER IS LIVE OUTSIDE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
THE SITE OF TODAY'S SHOOTING.
WHEN WE COME BACK, OUR
CONTINUING COVERAGE HERE ON
FOX NEWS CHANNEL.
KEEP IT HERE.
>> MY SON WAS AT THE GYM WHEN
IT HAPPENED SO I THINK HE
HEARD THE GUNSHOTS.
SO IT'S -- THEY WERE BOTH, I
THINK IT WILL BE ONE OF THOSE
THINGS WHERE YOU TRY TO
UNDERSTAND WHAT HAPPENED.
WHEN WE TELL THEM ULTIMATELY
WHAT HAPPENED IN DETAILS, I
THINK IT WILL MAKE IT MUCH
WORSE.
♪
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Sharable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
So we created the
extraordinarily
comfortable Sleep Number
Experience.
around a bed with DualAir
Technology that allows you
to adjust to the support
your body needs - each of
your bodies.
Our sleep professionals will
help you find
your sleep number setting.
Exclusively at a Sleep
Number store.
Sleep Number.
Comfort individualized.
This holiday season, give
the gift that's magical:
the innovative AirFit
adjustable pillow at
special 30% savings.
>>> CHILDREN, BEAUTIFUL,
BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN, WHO HAD
SIMPLY COME TO SCHOOL TO LEAR
LEARN.
AND THEIR DAY ENDED A VERY
DIFFERENT WAY THAN ANY OF US
COULD POSSIBLY HAVE IMAGINED.
QUITE FRANKLY, AS WE STAND
HERE TODAY, STILL CAN'T
IMAGINE WHAT TRANSPIRED THERE.
EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY
TODAY.
>> Bret: THAT WAS
CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR DAN
MALLOY.
AS WE HAVE BEEN TELLING YOU
THROUGHOUT THE AFTERNOON,
HEAVILY ARMED MAN OPENED FIRE
INSIDE A SCHOOL.
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
CONNECTICUT TODAY.
THE RESULTS WERE ALMOST
IMPOSSIBLE TO COMPREHEND.
20 CHILDREN KILLED.
AGE 5 TO 10.
SIX ADULTS.
THE SHOOTER ALSO DIED.
HE APPARENTLY KILLED AT LEAST
ONE OTHER ADULT BELIEVED TO BE
HIS MOTHER AT ANOTHER LOCATIO
LOCATION.
BILL HEMMER IS LIVE OUTSIDE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IN NEWTOWN AND JOINS US LIVE
THIS EVENING.
BILL, WE ARE JUST GETTING WORD
OF SOME NEWS ABOUT THE GUNS
THE SHOOTER USED.
>> YES, BRET.
FOX NEWS CAN CONFIRM THAT THE
THREE GUNS TIED TO THE GRISLY
MURDER SCENE WERE OWNED BY THE
SHOOTER'S MOTHER NANCY LANZA
WHO ALSO HAS A RELATIONSHIP AS
A TEACHER WITH THIS SCHOOL.
WHAT WE ARE STARTING TO PIECE
TOGETHER HERE IS THE TIMELINE,
THAT BEGAN AT DAYBREAK EARLIER
TODAY.
WHEN THIS YOUNG MAN GOT OUT OF
BED.
TOOK ONE OF THOSE GUN, SHOT
HIS MOTHER IN THE FACE.
TOOK HER CAR, AND DROVE TO THE
SCHOOL HERE, A SMALL
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN THE
PICTURESQUE PART OF
CONNECTICUT AND TAKING THE
LIVES OF 20 CHILDREN AGES 5
AND 6.
ALL IN KINDERGARTEN, SIX OTHER
ADULTS INSIDE.
THAT BUILDING AS WELL.
I TELL YOU, BRET, AFTER BEING
HERE FOR A COUPLE OF HOURS,
WHAT IS STRIKING THIS IS SMALL
TOWN AMERICA.
BEAUTIFUL WOODED AREA OF
ROLLING HILLS.
THIS TIME OF YEAR YOU THINK OF
CHRISTMASTIME A FEW WEEKS FROM
NOW AND IF THE SNOW STARTS TO
FALL AROUND HERE IT'S A
PICTURESQUE COMMUNITY.
ONE CAN ONLY IMAGINE HOW
BEAUTIFUL IT IS.
BUT THAT BEAUTY HAS BEEN
ABSOLUTELY SHATTERED BY THE
DESCRIPTION OF THE GRISLY
SCENE INSIDE OF THIS SCHOOL
BUILDING.
EARLIER TODAY, SOME OF THE
POLICE DESCRIBED IT AS NOT A
SIMPLISTIC SCENE.
IMAGINATION STARTS TO RUN YOU
START TO THINK ABOUT THESE
CHILDREN INSIDE THESE TWO
DIFFERENT ROOMS.
IN ONE SECTION OF THE SCHOOL.
THE BODIES HAVE NOT BEEN
REMOVED.
THEY ARE STILL INSIDE THAT
BUILDING BECAUSE POLICE SAY WE
NEED TO ANSWER EVERY QUESTION.
THAT WILL TAKE SOME TIME.
CERTAINLY TO TRY AND SORT THIS
OUT, AS WE WORK THROUGH THIS,
IN THE COMING HOURS AND THE
COMING DAYS.
SO MANY WONDERFUL WHY WOULD
THIS HAPPEN?
AND WHY -- SO MANY WONDERING
WHY WOULD THIS HAPPEN AND WHY
THE CHILDREN?
CERTAINLY, THEY DID NOT
DESERVE THIS.
>> Bret: ABOUT THOSE WEAPON,
WE'RE CONFIRMING THAT ALL
THREE WEAPONS WERE REGISTERED,
LEGALLY PURCHASED AND
REGISTERED TO THE GUNMAN'S
MOTHER.
ACCORDING TO LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS.
WE'RE ALSO BEING TOLD THERE
WAS 223 BUSHMASTER RIFLE AND
TWO HANDGUNS RECOVERED AT THE
SCHOOL.
THE AUTHORITIES NOT SAYING HOW
MANY SHOTS WERE FIRED.
BUT AS YOU MENTION, THAT SCENE
GRUESOME FOR ALL THE
AUTHORITIES WHO HAVE TO GO IN
THERE.
FOR THAT COMMUNITY TO DEAL
WITH, THAT YOU ARE THERE ON
THE GROUND.
THE NATION IS REACTING BUT
THERE ON THE GROUND, WHAT IS
IT LIKE?
>> THIS TOWN HAS ONE STOPLIGH
STOPLIGHT.
SANDY HOOK.
YOU CAN WALK THROUGH IT IN A
MINUTE'S TIME.
IT'S THAT SMALL.
YOU CAN IMAGINE HOW NEIGHBOR
KNOWS NEIGHBOR AND FAMILY
KNOWS FAMILY AND HOW IT WOULD
RIP APART ANY COMMUNITY MUCH
LESS THE TOWN OF SANDY HOOK
HERE IN SOUTHWESTERN
CONNECTICUT.
THE POLICE BY THE HOUR HAVE
BEEN GIVING US UPDATES BUT
I'LL BE FRANK, THERE ARE VERY
FEW FACTS COMING OUT ABOUT THE
STORY.
THAT TELLS ME THEY ARE PEELING
BACK THE LAYERS AND TRYING TO
PIECE IT TOGETHER.
YOU CAN IMAGINE THE CONFUSION
THAT RESULTED STARTING AT 9:30
THIS MORNING, TRYING TO FIND
HIS GUNMAN, LOCATE THE
RELATIONSHIP, WHO IS HE
RELATIONSHIP TO, MOTHER AND
HIS FATHER AND RELATIONSHIP
WITH HIS BROTHER.
ALL OF THIS STUFF IS STARTING
TO EVOLVE THROUGHOUT THE
NIGHT.
WE EXPECT A BRIEFING SOMETIME
SOON.
WHEN WE DO, MAYBE, SLOWLY,
BRET, WE CAN PIECE IT
TOGETHER.
MORE AT 7:00 ON THE "FOX
REPORT" LIVE FROM HERE.
>> Bret: WE'LL SEE YOU 20
MINUTES.
THANK YOU, BUDDY.
RETURN NOW TO WASHINGTON.
MORE WITH RICH MARIANOS WHO
WAS THE LEAD INVESTIGATOR IN
COLUMBINE IN 198 # 9.
YOU HEARD -- 1999.
YOU HEARD ABOUT THE GUNS THAT
WERE REGISTERED TO THE MOTHER
AND THAT IS SERIOUS FIRE POWER
FOR SHOOTER TO HAVE USED.
WHAT ABOUT THIS, IN THIS
INVESTIGATION.
WE HEAR ABOUT THE LONE WOLF
SHOOTERS AND THE AUTHORITIES
WORRIED ABOUT THEM.
TODAY'S TRAGEDY REALLY IS A
WORSE CASE SCENARIO WHERE IT
SEEMS LIKE THEY ARE DIGGING
FOR DEROGATORY INFORMATION
ABOUT THE GUY.
IT'S EARLY BUT WE ARE NOT
HEARING ANYTHING ABOUT THIS
GUY OR ANY HISTORY OF YET.
>> WELL, BECAUSE LAW
ENFORCEMENT WANTS TO CONDUCT A
PROFESSIONABLE INVESTIGATION.
THEY DON'T WANT TO RELEASE
EVIDENCE OR ANYTHING TO CREATE
PREJUDICE AMONG THE COMMUNITY,
JURY IF A CRIMINAL WILL BE
CHARGED.
AND WANTS TO KEEP A LITTLE BIT
OF RESPECT FOR THE FAMILY
MEMBERS WITHOUT TURNING THIS
IN TO A CIRCUS.
>> Bret: YEAH.
>> Guest: WE HAVE DONE A
GOOD JOB WITH THAT IN TERMS OF
LIMITING THE INFORMATION,
MAKING THIS WHAT IT'S ABOUT.
IT'S ABOUT THE TRAGEDY THAT
HAPPENED IN A COMMUNITY.
PUT A FULL COURT PRESS
TOGETHER WITH LAW ENFORCEMENT
COMPONENTS AND TRYING TO BE
RESPECTFUL THAT WE DON'T
JEOPARDIZE ANY PART OF AN
INVESTIGATION.
OR A POTENTIAL PROSECUTION.
OR CREATE DEBATE AMONG BOTH
SIDES.
JUST USING THIS ISSUE.
>> Bret: I FULLY UNDERSTAND
THAT, RICH.
I GUESS MY POINT IS HOW CAN
THE AUTHORITIES STOP SOMEONE
WHO PERHAPS HAS NO INDICATION
OF TROUBLE IN THE PAST?
THAT IS THE REAL CHALLENGE.
>> THE CHALLENGE FOR LAW
ENFORCEMENT, NOT JUST HERE BUT
EVERYWHERE.
WE NEED MORE COMMUNITY
APPROACH.
WE NEED EVERYONE WORKING
TOGETHER ON THIS ISSUE TO
IDENTIFY PEOPLE THAT, IDENTIFY
WHERE THE CRIMINALS ARE
PURCHASING FIRE ARMS.
TO IDENTIFY WHERE VIOLENT
CRIMES ARE TAKING PLACE AND
THE GUNS ARE USED.
TO IDENTIFY CRIMINALS THAT ARE
PUTTING THE GUNS IN THE HANDS
OF CRIMINALS.
YOU KNOW IT'S ABOUT CRIMES GUN
AND CRIME PROBLEM, VIOLENT
CRIME PROBLEM.
IN ORDER TO SOLVE THIS WE ALL
NEED TO WORK TOGETHER.
ALL FEDERAL AGENCIES, LOCAL
POLICE, COMMUNITY GROUP, GUN
DEALERS, THE MEDIA.
THE ONLY WAY WE'LL SOL TV IS A
COMBINED EFFORT AND MAKE THE
COUNTRY WHAT WE LOVE AND
RESPECT.
>> Bret: SURE.
THESE WERE LEGALLY PURCHASED
AND REGISTERED GUNS OF THE
MOTHER.
>> I'M NOT GOING TO COMMENT
ABOUT THE EVIDENCE RIGHT NOW
BECAUSE IT'S TOO EARLY TO
TELL.
WE DON'T HAVE WITNESSES TO PUT
THE GUN IN THE OFFENDER'S HAND
AT THIS TIME.
FOR TO US QUALIFY OR MAKE A
STATEMENT OF WHO PURCHASED
THEM WOULD BE UNFAIR TO
COMMUNITY AND UNFAIR TO THE
PUBLIC AND THE POOR FAMILY
MEMBERS DEALIN DEALING WITH THE
TRAGEDY.
I CAN GUARANTEE YOU, THOUGH,
ATF IS PUTTING A FULL COURT
PRESS GUARD IDENTIFYING IF THE
GUNS WERE PURCHASED ILLEGALLY
AND PUT HANDS OF VIOLENT
CRIMINAL WE'LL PUT A STOP TO
IT AND PUT PERSON BEHIND BARS
WITH ALL THE EVIDENTS WE HAVE.
>> Bret: RICH, I APPRECIATE
YOU STICKING AROUND.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH, BRET.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMPASSION
AND YOUR TIME ON THIS ISSUE.
>> Bret: WE CAN'T MAKE SENSE
OF THIS.
BUT WE CAN DISCUSS IT.
THE FOX ALL-STARS ARE NEXT.
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTING
AND THE ANALYSIS.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
♪
[hip-hop music]
- ♪ WHAT'S WRONG WITH
THE WORLD, MAMA ♪
♪ PEOPLE LIVIN' LIKE
THEY AIN'T GOT NO MAMAS ♪
♪ I THINK THE WHOLE WORLD'S
ADDICTED TO THE DRAMA ♪
♪ ONLY ATTRACTED TO THE THINGS
THAT'LL BRING THE TRAUMA ♪
♪ YEAH, MADNESS IS WHAT
YOU DEMONSTRATE ♪
♪ AND THAT'S EXACTLY HOW
ANGER WORKS AND OPERATES ♪
♪ MAN, YOU GOTTA HAVE LOVE
JUST TO SET IT STRAIGHT ♪
♪ TAKE CONTROL OF YOUR MIND
AND MEDITATE ♪
♪ LET YOUR SOUL GRAVITATE
TO THE LOVE, Y'ALL, Y'ALL ♪
- ♪ PEOPLE KILLING
PEOPLE DYING ♪
♪ CHILDREN HURT
AND YOU HEAR THEM CRYIN' ♪
♪ CAN YOU PRACTICE
WHAT YOU PREACH ♪
♪ WOULD YOU TURN
THE OTHER CHEEK ♪
- MA'AM.
- [gasps]
- YOU FORGOT YOUR PURSE.
- OH. YOU DON'T KNOW
HOW WORRIED I WAS.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
- HEY.
NICE MOVE, KID.
DOUGHNUT?
- A MESSAGE FROM THE
FOUNDATION FOR A BETTER LIFE.
I HAD[ Designer ]EELING
ENOUGH OF JUST COVERING UP
MY MODERATE TO SEVERE
PLAQUE PSORIASIS.
I DECIDED ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
♪
[ Spa Lady ]
I STARTED ENBREL.
IT'S CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO PROVIDE CLEARER SKIN.
[ RV Guy ] ENBREL MAY NOT WORK
FOR EVERYONE --
AND MAY NOT CLEAR YOU
COMPLETELY,
BUT FOR MANY, IT GETS SKIN
CLEARER FAST, WITHIN 2 MONTHS,
AND KEEPS IT CLEARER
UP TO 9 MONTHS.
[ Male Announcer ]
BECAUSE ENBREL®, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL,
EVENTS INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS, LYMPHOMA,
OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING ENBREL,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START ENBREL IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON ENBREL, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING,
OR PALENESS.
IF YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH, ASK
YOUR DERMATOLOGIST ABOUT ENBREL.
>>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN,
BEAUTIFUL KIDS BETWEEN THE
AGES OF FIVE AND TEN YEARS
OLD.
>> THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAY, GRADUATIONS, WEDDIN
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS, MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES TOPING
OUR CHILDREN FULFILL THEIR
DREAMS.
SO OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN
TODAY.
FOR THE PARENTS, AND
GRANDPARENTS, SISTERS AND
BROTHERS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN, AND FOR THE FAMILIES
OF THE ADULTS WHO WERE LOST.
>> Bret: AN EMOTIONAL
PRESIDENT OBAMA, REACTING TO
THE SCHOOL SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN
CONNECTICUT.
FOR ANALYSIS GO TO WASHINGTON,
D.C. AND PANEL.
FRED BARNES OF "WEEKLY
STANDARD."
KIRSTEN POWERS FOR DAILY
BEAST.
SYNDICATED COLUMNIST CHARLES
KRAUTHAMMER.
CHARLES, WORDS TODAY?
>> THE FIRST THING TO SAY IN
LOOKING AT THIS OR ANALYZING
THIS REQUIRES A HUGE AMOUNT OF
HUMILITY.
THE TRUE FACT IS WE DO NOT
KNOW AND OFTEN EVEN AFTER
THESE EVENTS ARE ANALYZEED AND
THOUGHT THROUGH, WE REALLY
DON'T KNOW.
THIS IS THE PROBLEM OF EVIL.
AND IT'S BEEN STRUGGLED WITH
FOREVER.
WHAT WE KNOW ABOUT THE CURRENT
SHOOTING IS THAT PEOPLE ARE
DIVIDED IN THREE CAMPS.
THREE ELEMENTS.
PSYCHOLOGY OF THE SHOOTER, YOU
HAVE THE WEAPON, AND YOU'VE
GOT THE CULTURAL ENVIRONMENT.
PEOPLE WILL CHOOSE WHICHEVER
CAUSE THEY WANT TO BLAME.
THEY WILL SAY IT'S GUNS THAT
WERE AVAILABLE.
LAWS OUGHT TO BE TIGHTENED,
ALTHOUGH THE BRADY CAMPAIGN
SAYS CONNECTICUT HAS THE FOUR
STRICTEST LAWS IN THE COUNTRY.
THEN YOU HAVE THE ENVIRONMENT.
PEOPLE ON THE RIGHT, TEND TO
SAY THAT OUR CULTURE DECEN
DECENTTIZING YOUNG --
DE-SENSITIZING PEOPLE IN
MOVIES AND VIDEO GAMES TO KILL
IN WAY OLDER GENERATION FIND
DISTURBING.
I TEND TO GRAVITATE TOWARD THE
PSYCHOLOGY OF THE KILLER.
WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT THE
DETAILS OF THE CRIME, HE BEGAN
BY SHOOTING HIS MOTHER IN THE
FACE.
TAKING HER WEAPON AND THEN
DESTROYING EVERYTHING PRECIOUS
TO HER.
HER COLLEAGUES AND HER
CHILDREN.
THEN KILLING HIMSELF.
THAT I THINK IS WHERE I WOULD
START.
ALTHOUGH I THINK ALL THE
ISSUES HAVE TO BE DISCUSSED.
>> Bret: KIRSTEN?
>> YES, I THINK ALL THE ISSUES
HAVE TO BE DISCUSSED BUT THE
PSYCHOLOGY PART HAS TO BE
PAIRED WITH THE SEMI-AUTOMATIC
WEAPON IN ORDER FOR SOMETHING
LIKE THIS TO HAPPEN.
AS THE PRESIDENT SAID TODAY WE
NEED TO HAVE SOME MEANINGFUL
ACTION, TO DEAL WITH THIS
ISSUE.
THIS IS SOMETHING NOW THAT IS
STARTING TO ALMOST BECOME
EPIDEMIC IN OUR COUNTRY.
IT'S NOT -- IN MY ENTIRE
CHILDHOOD I DON'T -- YOU KNOW,
IF IT HAPPENED, THIS WAS SUCH
A RARITY.
IT'S NOW ALMOST COMMONPLACE.
THIS SHOOTINGS.
THIS IS PARTICULARLY TERRIBLE
BECAUSE IT INVOLVED ALL THE
YOUNG CHILDREN.
5-YEAR-OLD.
THE INNOCENT OF THE INNOCENT
YOU CAN THINK OF.
BUT I THINK WE HAVE TO LOOK AT
THE FACTORS, MENTAL HEALTH
FACTORS.
ARE WE LOOKING FOR SIGNS, ARE
WE OFFERING MENTAL HEALTH
TREATMENT TO PEOPLE?
BUT ALSO LOOKING AT THE GUN
LAWS, DO WE HAVE THE RIGHT GUN
LAWS?
ALL THE DIFFERENTS A SPENTS OF
IT -- ASPECTS OF IT AND TRY TO
SERIOUSLY ADDRESS THE ISSUE
AND NOT JUST THROW UP OUR HAND
AND SAY WELL, THERE IS NOTHING
WE CAN DO ABOUT IT.
THESE THINGS JUST HAPPEN.
THESE THINGS JUST SHOULDN'T
HAPPEN.
>> Bret: FRED, ATTORNEY
GENERAL HOLDER EARLIER TALKED
ABOUT FREEDOMS AND AGE LOSING
WHAT HAPPENED TODAY --
ANALYZING WHAT HAPPENED TODAY
IN CONTRAST OR CONTEXT OF OUR
FREEDOMS.
>> WELL, ONE OF THE FREEDOMS
WE HAVE HAD IN THIS COUNTRY
RATIFIED BY THE SUPREME COURT
THE RIGHT TO BEAR ARMS.
INDIVIDUALS CAN DO IT AN THEY
DO.
BUT THERE ARE OTHER COUNTRIES
WHERE ARMS ARE PLENTIFUL,
COUNTRYS LIKE ISRAEL AND
SWITZERLAND WE DON'T HAVE THE
SAME HOMICIDE RATE WE HAVE IN
THE UNITED STATES.
WE DON'T HAVE THE MASS
KILLINGS OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
MY ARE ACTION WAS OH, NOT
AGAIN.
THAT WAS A LOT OF PEOPLE'S
REACTION.
THE PROBLEM IS THE UNITED
STATES IS ONE THAT CHARLES
MENTIONED; THE PSYCHOLOGY OF
THE PEOPLE WHO DO THE
KILLINGS, VIRGINIA TECH,
COLUMBINE, THEATER IN AURORA,
COLORADO AND ALL THE KILLINGS.
WE HAVE TO FIND WAYS TO KEEP
GUNS OUT OF THE HANDS OF THESE
PEOPLE.
IT'S HARD TO DO.
LOOK, THE GUNS BELONG TO THIS
KILLER'S MOTHER.
SHE HAD THEM AT THE HOME.
THE SON NOT OLD ENOUGH TO OWN
A FIREARM GOT THEM AND TOOK
THEM AND USED THEM.
I DON'T KNOW HOW YOU COULD
REALLY STOP THAT.
EVEN IN A STATE, AS CHARLES
SAID, WITH PRETTY STRICT GUN
CONTROL LAWS.
THE PROBLEM IS WE DO HAVE --
COMPARED TO OTHER COUNTRIES
WITH A LOT OF GUN, A CULTURE
OF VIOLENCE IN THIS COUNTRY
THAT ALLOWS, THAT ALLOWS A LOT
OF VIOLENT ACTS TO HAPPEN.
THEY WEREN'T CUS CURBED WELL HEE
AND PEOPLE DO GET GUNS.
LOOK, WE ARE NOT GOING TO BEEN N
GUNS IN THIS COUNTRY.
WE CAN CURB THE NUMBER OF THEM
BUT THESE WERE LEGALLY OWNED
GUNS AND WERE USED BY
PRESUMABLY, A PSYCHOTIC
PERSON.
HARD TO STOP THAT.
>> Bret: CHARLES, IF YOU A
PARENT TONIGHT PUT ON THE
PSYCHIATRIST HAT AND YOUR
CHILD, WHAT DO YOU SAY TO
THEM?
>> I MEAN WEFULLY A CULTURE
YOU CAN'T ESCAPE FROM THE
EVENTS.
WHICH CITIZEN TRAGIC.
SO EVERYBODY IS EXPOSED.
ALL YOU CAN DO IS PROVIDE THEM
SAFETY AND LOVE.
NO EXPLANATIONS THAT'S NOT
WHAT YOU DO.
SHOW THEM YOU WILL PROTECT
THEM, BECAUSE YOU LOVE THEM.
THEY DO NOT HAVE TO FEAR.
THAT IS ALL YOU CAN SAY.
>> Bret: PANEL, AS ALWAYS,
TOUGH DAY, BUT THANK YOU.
NEXT UP, REACTION FROM ALL
OVER THE COUNTRY TO TODAY'S
EVENTS.
♪
>> Bret: NOW REACTION FROM
AROUND THE COUNTRY.
CHIEF WASHINGTON CORRESPONDENT
JAMES ROSE SEASON LIVE TONIGHT
IN D.C.
HELLO, JAMES.
>> BRET, GOOD EVENING.
THERE WERE SOME FOLKS THAT I
SPOKE WITH THIS AFTERNOON WHO
HADN'T HEARD ABOUT THE
MASSACRE, SOME OVERSEAS
TOURIST, PEOPLE STEPPING OUT
OF MUSEUMS BUT MOST HAD HEARD.
LIKE YOU AND ME THEY WERE
CHANGED FOREVER.
>> MAYBE 45 OR --
>> FOR MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
THE GRUESOME NEWS CAME IN BITS
AND PIECES.
>> FIRST, THEY LEARNED THERE
HAD BEEN A SCHOOL SHOOTING,
THEN A FATAL ONE, THEN A
TRAGEDY OF UNFATHOMABLE
PROPORTIONS.
>> WHY ARE PEOPLE DOING THINGS
LIKEBE THIS?
I DON'T UNDERSTAND WHAT MAKES
PEOPLE EVIL THAT WOULD JUST
WANT TO GO AND KILL INNOCENT
PEOPLE.
>> IT'S JUST THE WORST, MOST
DEVASTATING STUFF.
REALLY SAD TO REALIZE OUR
SOCIETY HAS COME TO THIS
PLACE.
>> I'M SORRY.
IT'S CRAZY.
I CAN'T BELIEVE PEOPLE ARE
DOING THAT.
>> IT IS VERY UPSETTING,
CHILDREN, WHO HAVEN'T LIVED,
HAVEN'T EXPERIENCEED ANYTHING.
AND TAKEN SO EARLY.
IT IS VERY SHOCKING.
>> WHAT WAS SUPPOSED TO BE A
SEASON OF JOY DARKENED, AS
MANUALS OF CHILDREN HEARDED
OUT OF SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, THE LUCKY KIDS WHO
MADE IT OUT ALIVE AND STILL
MAY FACE YEARS OF TRAUMA FROM
THE EVENT CUT TO THE CORE OF
PARENTS EVERYWHERE.
>> I CRIED AND I CRIED AND MY
DAUGHTER CALLED ME WHO HAS A
CHILD IN KINDER GARDEN, FIRST
GRADE AND IN SECOND GRADE AND
SHE COULDN'T STOP CRYING.
SO IT'S A TRAGEDY.
AS I SAID TO HER, YOU CAN'T
UNDERSTAND THINGS LIKE THAT.
>> IT'S DEVASTATING.
IT REALLY SHOOK ME.
BECAUSE I HAVE, YOU KNOW, SON
HERE IN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, AND
I CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT THE
PARENTS GO THROUGH, THE
PARENTS GETTING THE COOLS.
IT'S SO UNFORTUNATE.
IT'S TRAGIC.
IT REALLY HATE THAT IT EVEN
HAPPENED.
IT'S JUST SO SAD.
>> FROM COLUMBINE THROUGH
VIRGINIA TECH AND THE MOVIE
THEATER IN AURORA UP THROUGH
THIS WEEK'S MALL SHOOTING
OUTSIDE OF PORTLAND, OREGON,
AMERICANS HAVE BECOME --
[ INAUDIBLE ]
IDEA OF MASS SHOOTING BUT NOT
TO THE HORROR, CRUELTY AND
ENDURING EMOTIONAL IMPACT OF
THEM.
>> THE COMMUNITY, CREATE A
COMMUNITY THAT IS STRONG AND A
COMMUNITY THAT DOES SORT OF
HAVE THOSE UNSAID BARRIERS.
WE DON'T ACCEPT THAT HERE.
WE ARE TOGETHER.
WE'RE COHESIVE.
>> WE HAVE A SOCIETAL
BREAKDOWN.
I'M A TEACHER, SO I SEE IT AT
AN OPERATIONAL LEVEL.
THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO TAKE EASY
ACCESS TO THINGS TO FILL A
FANTASY OR GO NUT THEIR BLAZE
OF GLORY OR WHATEVER PROMPTS
THEM.
>> I AM GLAD THAT OUR DOORS
ARE LOCKED AT ALL TIMES.
YOU CAN'T GET IN THEM.
THAT WAS MY FIRST REACTION.
THEN WALKING UP TO SCHOOL
TODAY, I THOUGHT TO MYSELF,
YOU KNOW, I FEEL FOR THE
PARENTS.
IT COULDN'T EVEN IMAGINE WHAT
THEY ARE GOING THROUGH.
>> MY MOTHER REGINA ROSENNEN
OF STATEN ISLAND, NEW YORK,
WROTE HUG YOUR CHILDREN FOR ME
WHEN YOU GET HOME.
THIS HAS PLUNGED THE WHOLE
COUNTRY IN TO TERRIBLE
SADNESS.
BRET?
>> Bret: THANK YOU.
SOME FINAL THOUGHTS ON A
TRAGIC DAY.
There is no
mass-produced human.
So we created the
extraordinarily
comfortable Sleep Number
Experience.
around a bed with DualAir
Technology that allows you
to adjust to the support
your body needs - each of
your bodies.
Our sleep professionals will
help you find
your sleep number setting.
Exclusively at a Sleep
Number store.
Sleep Number.
Comfort individualized.
This holiday season, give
the gift that's magical:
the innovative AirFit
adjustable pillow at
special 30% savings.
SHE ALSO LIKES TO RIDE
HER BIKE.
SHE KNOWS THE POTENTIAL
FOR MAKING OR LOSING MONEY
CAN POP UP ANYTIME.
THAT'S WHY SHE TRADES WITH
THE LEADER IN MOBILE TRADING.
SO SHE'S ALWAYS READY
TO TAKE ACTION,
NO MATTER HOW WILY...
OR WEIRD...
OR WONDERFULLY
THE MARKET'S BEHAVING...
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
>> FINALLY TONIGHT, SOME OF THE
IMAGES FROM THE SCHOOL SHOOTING
IN CONNECTICUT, PICTURES OF THE
SURVIVORS AND THE PARENTS OF
SOME OF THE CHILDREN AND THE
ADULTS ON THE SCENE To[gu1Cuo<,
REMARKABLY PLOWING THROUGH THEIR
EMOTIONS TO DO THEIR JOBS AND
SECURE THE SCENE.
PERHAPS YOU CAN BEGIN THE SENSE
OF FLOOD OF SORROW AND FEAR AND
AGER AND CONFUSION THAT GRIPPED
THIS COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN TODAY
AND REALLY ALL OVER AMERICA.
IT IS A DAY NO ONE THERE, NONE
OF THEM, WILL EVER FORGET.
NEWTOWN WILL NOW LIVE IN OUR
COLLECTIVE CONSCIOUSNESS, ALONG
WITH NAMES LIKE COLUMBINE AND
AURORA, COLORADO AND VIRGINIA
TECH.
AND AGAIN TODAY, THE NATION
RECOILS TOGETHER, RALLIES
TOGETHER, GRIEVES TOGETHER,
PRAYS TOGETHER IN RECOGNITION OF
THE VALUE