I'M
JENNA LEE IN NEWTOWN, ON THE
GROUND TO GET PA BETTER IDEA
WHAT TRANSPIRED YESTERDAY
MORNING.
AFTER ONLY A FEW HOURS, I CAN
TELL YOU ABOUT NEWTOWN, IT
BECOMES CLEAR RIGHT AWAY.
THIS IS A PARTICULARLY CLOSE
NIGHT COMMUNITY DEEPLY IN
GRIEF.
WHERE I AM RIGHT NOW IS ABOUT
A MILE OR SO FROM THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
IF YOU LIKE BEHIND ME YOU'RE
GOING TO SEE THE BASEBALL
FIELD HERE, I'M IN WHAT IS NOW
BEING USED AS THE MEDIA
STAGING AREA, BUT IT'S A
COMMUNITY FIELD OF SORTS FOR
ELEMENTARY AND HIGH SCHOOL
STUDENTS AS WELL AS THE
GENERAL COMMUNITY OVERALL,
SOCCER FIELD AND TENNIS
COURTS, ALL NOW FILLED WITH
MEDIA PERSONNEL COMING IN.
AND OON DRIVING IN THIS
MORNING, A SLEEPY TOWN IN
CONNECTICUT, A BRISK COOL,
LIKE WE SAW YESTERDAY.
THERE'S REALLY NO ONE ON THE
STREETS, ONE LONE JOGGER AND
THE REST, AGAIN, JOURNALISTS
TRYING TO GATHER INFORMATION
FOR EVERYONE IN THIS COUNTRY
THAT HAS SO MANY QUESTIONS
ABOUT WHAT TRANSPIRED
YESTERDAY.
NOW, WE'VE HEARD THERE'S GOING
TO BE A PRESS CONFERENCE
SHORTLY AND WAITING ON THAT
FOR ABOUT TWO HOURS AND I CAN
SEE THE MICROPHONES, ABOUT 50
FEET AWAY FROM ME SO WE'LL
BRING OUR VIEWERS THERE WHEN
WE GET THE LATEST INFORMATION
FROM OFFICIALS.
WE WERE ABLE TO SPEAK WITH ONE
WOMAN WHO WAS INSIDE THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, JUST A FEW
MOMENTS AGO.
HER NAME, MARY ANNE JACOBS AND
SHE'S A SCHOOL LIBRARY CLERK
AND YOU'RE GOING TO SEE HER ON
THE SCREEN THERE AND THAT'S
HER HUSBAND SHE WAS HUGGING
AFTER SPEAKING TO JOURNALISTS.
MARY ANNE'S STORIES, YESTERDAY
SHE WAS WITH 18 FOURTH GRADERS
IN THE LIBRARIES AND SHE HEARD
A NOISE OVER THE INTERS COME,
AND RUMBLINGS AND DO YOU KNOW
IF YOUR INTERCOM IS ON.
AND THE SECRETARY SAID THERE'S
A SHOOTING.
AND SHE SAYS THAT SECRETARY IS
A HERO TODAY.
AND SHE WENT OUT INTO THE
HALLS, AND SAID WE'RE IN
LOCKDOWN AND RETURNED TO THE
LIBRARY AND TOOK HER 18 FOURTH
GRADERS BEHIND STACKS OF BOOKS
AND THEY WERE TRYING TO HIDE
AND REALIZED THEY DIDN'T HAVE
THE COVERAGE THEY NEEDED AND
DOORS WERE NOT LOCKED.
UPON HEARING THAT AND LEARNING
THAT, MARY ANNE AND A FEW
OTHERS IN THE ROOM MOVED THE
18 FOURTH GRADERS INTO A
STORAGE CLOSET.
LOCKED THE DOOR AND PUSHED A
FILE CABINET AGAINST IT, THEY
WERE LUCKY ENOUGH THAT THEY
HAD SOME CELL PHONE RECEPTION
IN THAT STORAGE ROOM, THEY
WERE ABLE TO REACH THE OUTSIDE
AND MARY ANNE SAID THEY WERE
ALSO LUCKY BECAUSE THEY HAD
SOME PAPER AND SOME CRAYONS
AND ASKING SOME QUESTIONS AND
THEY WERE ASKING QUESTIONS,
BUT KEEPING THEM CALM AND AS
THEY COULD HEAR WHAT THEY KNEW
WERE GUNSHOTS IN THE SCHOOL
AND MARY ANNE DOESN'T KNOW THE
TIME LINE FOR SURE, BUT THINKS
THEY WERE THERE FOR ABOUT AN
HOUR AND HEARD BANGING ON THE
DOOR AND SHE DIDN'T WANT TO
OPEN IT AS I'M SURE YOU COULD
IMAGINE AND SHE GOT A CALL THE
POLICE WERE OUT THERE AND
MOVED THE FILE CABINET AND
ASKED FOR A BADGE UNDERNEATH
THE DOOR AND OUTSIDE THERE
WERE 15 STATE POLICE OUTSIDE
AND AT THAT MOMENTS SHE SAYS
SHE KNEW THAT THE CHILDREN
KNEW THIS WAS DIFFERENT.
AT THAT TIME, JOHN, THEY WENT
TO THE FIREHOUSE AND AS WE
WERE COVERING YESTERDAY, THAT
WAS REALLY AN AREA WHERE ALL
THE CHILDREN WENT AND MARY
ANNE SAYS SHE WAS THERE FOR
THE REST OF THE AFTERNOON.
WE'RE GOING TO PLAY SOME OF
HER STORY FOR OUR VIEWERS,
JON, IN JUST A LITTLE BIT.
AS YOU CAN TELL THE NEWS
CONFERENCE WHILE WE'RE WAITING
FOR THAT, BUT NEW INFORMATION
AS WELL THIS MORNING, JON.
>> JENNA THERE IN NEWTOWN,
JENNA, THANKS.
WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE
VICTIMS AND THE GUNMAN.
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA.
POLICE SAY HE SHOT AND KILLED
HIS MOTHER AT THEIR HOME RIGHT
THERE IN NEWTOWN BEFORE
DRIVING TO THE SCHOOL AND
UNLEASHING HIS RAGE.
THIS IS A 2005 PHOTO OF THE
GUNMAN.
IT IS ABSOLUTELY INEXPLICABLE
WHAT HE HAS WROUGHT ON THAT
TINY COMMUNITY AND REALLY ON
THE ENTIRE NATION AND WE'RE
HOPING TO LEARN MORE FROM THAT
NEWS CONFERENCE THAT WE'VE
BEEN EXPECTING NOW FOR THE
BETTER PART OF TWO HOURS, WHEN
THIS NEWS CONFERENCE DOES
BEGIN.
WE'LL CERTAINLY TAKE YOU BACK
THERE LIVE.
JENNA?
>> JON, PETER DOOCY HAS BEEN
ON THE GROUND THIS MORNING AS
WELL AND REPORTING ON THIS
STORY AND PETER, WE'RE TRYING
TO PIECE TOGETHER THE BEST WE
CAN, THE FACTS OF WHAT
HAPPENED YESTERDAY.
WHAT HAVE YOU LEARNED SO FAR?
>> JEN, AGAIN, WE'VE BEEN
WAITING FOR THE NEWS
CONFERENCE MORE THAN TWO HOURS
NOW, BUT THE LAST UPDATE WE
GOT FROM THE LOCAL POLICE HERE
IS, AS OF ABOUT 7:30, 7:40
THIS MORNING IS THAT AT THAT
TIME, THERE WERE STILL SOME
BODIES THAT REMAINED INSIDE
THE SCHOOL BUILDING.
AND SOME BODIES HAD BEEN
REMOVED AND HAD BEEN I.D. 'D,
BUT SOME BODIES REMAINED IN
THERE AND AGAIN, THE LAST
UPDATE WE GOT WAS NOT ON
CAMERA, BUT IT WAS FROM THE
LOCAL AUTHORITIES WHO ALSO
TOLD US THAT THEY HAVE PLENTY
OF EVIDENCE INSIDE AND OUTSIDE
AND THAT SOME OF THE INSIDE
EVIDENCE INCLUDES WEAPONS, IN
ADDITION TO THE THREE THAT WE
KNEW ABOUT YESTERDAY.
WE KNEW YESTERDAY THAT HE HAD
A GLOCK AND ANOTHERPI PISTOL
INSIDE HIS CAR AND THERE WERE
VEHICLES OUTSIDE, INCLUDING
THE SUSPECT'S VEHICLE THEY
WANT TO LOOK AT.
SOMETHING ELSE THAT WAS BRAND
NEW, THE LAST UPDATE WE GOT
FROM THE AUTHORITIES.
THEY SAY IT NOW APPEARED TO
GAIN PACK CESS ACCESS TO THE SCL
THE BECOME SHOT OUT THE GLASS
IN THE FRONT DOOR AND WE
TALKED TO ANOTHER TEACHER IN
THE SCHOOL, FROM ANOTHER
DISTRICT WHO IS FAMILIAR WITH
THE SECURITY PROCEDURES.
AS SOON AS ANYONE WANTS TO GET
IN, INCLUDING A PARENT, THEY
NEED TO BASICALLY APPEAR ON A
CAMERA THAT THEN PRESENTS
THEIR IMAGE TO SOMEONE IN THE
FRONT OFFICE AND THEN SOMEONE
IN THE FRONT OFFICE NEEDS TO
BUZZ THE DOOR, LIKE IN AN
APARTMENT BUILDING, TO LET
THEM IN AND THEN THAT PERSON
NEEDS TO GO IMMEDIATELY TO THE
OFFICE.
THE OFFICERS ARE NOW SAYING
THAT IT APPEARS THE GUNMAN
SHOT HIS WAY IN.
>> IT'S INTERESTING, WITH THE
TIMING ON THIS, AGAIN, WE'RE
TRYING TO PIECE TOGETHER
EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED.
BUT WE KNOW THAT THE SCHOOL
PUTS THE SECURITY PROCEDURES
IN PLACE, LOCKED THEIR DOORS
AROUND 9:30 IN THE MORNING.
BUT, THE TIME LINE, TELL US A
LITTLE ABOUT THE RESPONSE
TIME.
BECAUSE IT SEEMS LIKE AT LEAST
FROM WHAT WE KNOW, THAT THIS
HAPPENED VERY QUICKLY.
>> IT DOES SEEM LIKE IT
HAPPENED QUICKLY AND SOMETHING
ELSE THAT MARY ANNE JACOB TOLD
US, YOU MENTION THAT SHE
CALLED THE SECRETARY AND THE
SECRETARY PICKED UP THE PHONE,
EVEN THOUGH THE GUN--
SHE WAS APPARENTLY IN SIGHT OF
THE GUNMAN AND SAID THEY'RE
SHOOTING AND THEN THE TEACHER,
OR THE LIBRARY CLERK, RAN OUT
AND YELLED LOCKDOWN, WITHIN
THAT TIME, THEY LOCKED DOWN
MOST OF THE CLASSROOMS.
WE ALSO HEARD FROM THAT
LIBRARY CLERK, HER
UNDERSTANDING EVEN THOUGH SHE
WAS IN THE BACK OF THE SCHOOL
WITH THE FOURTH GRADERS, HER
UNDERSTANDING IS THAT THE
GUNMAN ENTERED THE FRONT DOOR
AND THEN SKIPPED THE FIRST
CLASSROOM AND WENT AND SHOT UP
THE SECOND AND THIRD CLASSROOM
IN A ROW AND SHE SAID THAT
WHEN THEY WERE AT THE
FIREHOUSE, ALL THE TEACHERS
LINED UP BY GRADE AND THEY HAD
ALL THE STUDENTS LINED UP
BEHIND THEM FROM THEIR CLASSES
SO THEY COULD GET A HEAD
COUNTS AND IT WAS AT THE
FIREHOUSE, SHORTLY AFTER, SHE
SAID I THINK AROUND 10:30 OR
11:30 IN THE MORNING, THAT
THEY REALIZED WHEN THEY WERE
DOING THE HEAD COUNT BY CLASS,
THAT TWO ENTIRE CLASSES SHE
THINKS THEY WERE FIRST GRADE
CLASSES WERE NOT THERE EXCEPT
FOR FEW KIDS.
>> WE'VE HEARD SO MANY
DIFFERENT CONFLICTING REPORTS
AND OUR VIEWERS HAVE HEARD A
KINDERGARTEN CLASS AND WE'VE
HEARD NOW FROM A FEW PEOPLE
HERE, FIRST GRADE.
BUT ONE OF THE THINGS WE'RE
REALLY WAITING FOR IS
CONFIRMATION OF THE NAMES OF
THE DECEASED.
>> AND WE WERE TOLD THE LAST
UPDATE WE GOT AROUND EIGHT
O'CLOCK AT NIGHT AND
AUTHORITIES AT THAT POINT
ANNOUNCEDED MEDICAL EXAMINER'S
OFFICE AFTER A FULL DAY OF
POLICE INVESTIGATION AS
ALLOWED IN AND IDENTIFYING THE
YOUNG VICTIMS ON SITE AND
REPORTED BY LOCAL OUTLETS HERE
THAT A TEMPORARY MORGUE WAS
SET UP SOMEWHERE ON THE SCHOOL
GROUNDS AND THAT'S WHERE THE
AUTHORITIES WENT AND TOOK
PHOTOGRAPHS OF THE YOUNG
VICTIMS AND THE AUTHORITIES
WOULD THEN TAKE THOSE
PHOTOGRAPHS TO SHOW THE
PARENTS AND WE'RE TOLD THAT
THAT WAS SOMETHING THAT WAS
GOING ON THROUGHOUT THE NIGHT.
ONE AT A TIME.
AND IT'S TOUGH TO--
>> IT'S TOUGH TO REPORT.
>> AND THINK ABOUT.
>> I THINK IT'S SOMETHING THAT
WE'VE ALL ENCOUNTERED HERE.
YOU KNOW, JON, PETTER AND I
WERE SITTING WAITING FOR THE
PRESS CONFERENCE TO BEGIN AND
EVEN AMONG SOME OF OUR FELLOW
JOURNALISTS WAITING FOR THE
NEWS CONFERENCE AND SOME WERE
EXCHANGING STORIES AND HOW
THEY WERE CONNECTED TO WHAT
HAPPENED AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
MANY OF THEM IN TEARS.
AND IT JUST SORT OF SHOWS US
HOW CLOSE KNIT IN COMMUNITY?
AND MANY POINTED OUT IT'S NOT
JUST NEWTOWN, THERE'S A SERIES
OF TOWNS AROUND THIS AREA AND
EVERYONE HAS TO PASS THROUGH
EACH OTHER'S TOWNS TO GET TO
WHERE THEY'RE GOING, SO A VERY
CLOSE KNIT COMMUNITY AND SO
MANY AFFECTED HERE.
>> I THINK EVERYBODY CAN
PERHAPS UNDERSTAND HOW AWFUL
IT IS TO HAVE THIS KIND OF
TRAGEDY, THIS KIND OF MAYHEM
SUDDENLY INVADE THEIR
COMMUNITIES WHEN IT'S
ABSOLUTELY SO UNEXPECTED.
AND AS JENNA WAS JUST SAYING,
THE CONNECTICUT AUTHORITIES
HAVE BEEN WORKING THROUGH THE
NIGHT, TRYING TO POSITIVELY
IDENTIFY THE BODIES.
LET'S TALK ABOUT THAT PROCESS
WITH DR. MICHAEL BADEN, A
FORENSIC PSYCHOLOGIST AND ALSO
A FOX NEWS CONTRIBUTOR.
ADULTS CARRY I.D. GENERALLY,
IN FACT, WITH THE GUNMAN IN
THIS CASE, THE FACT THAT HE
WAS APPARENTLY CARRYING HIS
BROTHER'S I.D. IS PART OF WHAT
LED TO THE MISIDENTIFICATION.
THAT DOESN'T HAPPEN WITH
CHILDREN.
SO WHAT IS THE PROCESS?
>> WELL, THE PROCESS NOW IS
MORE INSTEAD OF TAKING THE
FAMILY TO SEE THE BODY,
ESPECIALLY IN THE SCHOOL, IS
TO TAKE PHOTOGRAPHS OF THE
FACE OF THE CHILD AND SHOW
THEM TO THE FAMILY MEMBERS WHO
ARE WAITING, IDENTIFY EACH
BODY BY PHOTOGRAPH AND THEN
THEY CAN REMOVE THE BODY TO
FARMINGTON IS THE MAIN MEDICAL
EXAMINER'S OFFICE.
DO WHATEVER FURTHER EVALUATION
IS NECESSARY BECAUSE THEY'VE
GOT TO DESCRIBE AND ESTABLISH
EACH BULLET WOUND, THEY
PROBABLY, THEY HAVE TO TAKE
NOT ONLY PHOTOGRAPHS, BUT ALSO
X-RAYS AND THEY HAVE TO HAVE
THE X-RAY MACHINES TO SEE IF
THERE ARE ANY BULLETS IN THE
BODIES.
>> DOES IT HAVE TO BE A PARENT
WHO MAKES THE IDENTIFICATION?
COULD IT BE A RELATIVE.
>> A RELATIVE OR CLOSE FRIEND.
IT DOESN'T HAVE TO BE THE
PARENT.
THAT'S RIGHT, SOMETIMES THE
PARENTS CAN BE SPARED THAT BY
OTHERS WHO KNOW THE FAMILY
WELL.
>> IN YOUR EXPERIENCE, I MEAN,
I JUST CAN'T IMAGINE HAVING TO
DO THAT.
I'VE GOT FOUR KIDS MYSELF.
I CAN'T IMAGINE HAVING TO DO
IT.
IN YOUR EXPERIENCE DO PARENTS
WANT TO--
NOT CHILDREN.
>> BE INVOLVED?
>> CHILDREN ARE SUPPOSED TO
IDENTIFY PARENTS.
>> EXACTLY.
>> NOT THE REVERSE, AND THIS
IS SUCH A LARGE TRAGEDY AND I
THINK PART OF WHAT'S BEING
LOOKED INTO NOW IS WHY DID
ADAM DO THIS AND IT APPEARS TO
ME THAT THERE WAS SOMETHING
WITH HIS MOTHER THAT HE KILLED
HIS MOTHER FIRST AND MAYBE HE
WAS JEALOUS THAT HIS MOTHER
THOUGHT MORE OF THE
KINDERGARTEN CHILDREN SHE MAY
HAVE WORKED WITH AT ONE TIME
THAN HIM AND HE GOES OUT IN A
CRAZY WAY, KILLS ALL THE
CHILDREN, JUST VERY UNIQUE AND
VERY UNPREDICTABLE.
>> IT'S GIT'S GOT TO BE
FRUSTRATING FOR THE PARENTS,
WE'RE GOING ON MORE THAN 24
HOURS THE MAYHEM ERUPTED AND
FOR MORE THAN 24 HOURS,
THEY'RE UNABLE TO TOUCH THEIR
CHILDREN.
>> AND MAKE FUNERAL
ARRANGEMENTS.
AND THAT'S WHY THEY HAVE A
FIRST RATE MEDICAL SYSTEM IN
CONNECTICUT THEY KNOW THEY'VE
GOT TO GET THE BODIES TO THE
PARENTS AS SOON AS POSSIBLE
AND THAT'S WHY THEY'VE WORKED
ALL NIGHT AND MANY OF THE
BODIES, IF NOT ALL, SOME.
TRANSFERRED AT MIDNIGHT WHEN
NOBODY WAS AROUND TO TAKE
PICTURES AND ALL AND WENT TO
FARMINGTON AND THEY'RE WORKING
24 HOURS STILL TO COMPLETE
WHATEVER THEY HAVE TO DO WITH
EACH BODY AND THEN RELEASE THE
BODIES TO THE FAMILY FOR THE
FUNERAL ARRANGEMENTS WHICH I
ASSUME THEY'LL START TOMORROW.
>> AS YOU CAN SEE ON YOUR
SCREEN THERE, WE ARE SEEING
SOME MOVEMENT AT THE SITE OF
THE NEWS CONFERENCE, AND THIS
NEWS CONFERENCE WAS SCHEDULED
FOR EIGHT O'CLOCK THIS
MORNING, IT'S NOW 10:13
EASTERN TIME, SO, MORE THAN
2 1/2 HOURS LATE.
THERE APPEARS TO BE SOME
MOVEMENT AND SO PERHAPS WE'LL
GET SOME ANSWERS TO SOME OF
THESE QUESTIONS THAT WE'VE
BEEN LOOKING FOR.
DR. BADEN, THEY ALSO PUT OUT A
CALL FOR EXTRA HELP AND THE
CORONER'S OFFICE WAS
OVERWHELMED.
DOES THERE HAVE TO BE AN
AUTOPSY FOR EVERY SINGLE
CHILD?
>> THAT, THE MEDICAL EXAMINER
WILL HAVE TO DECIDE.
IF THERE IS A BULLET IN THE
BODY THEY HAVE TO DO AN
INTERNAL EXAMINATION TO REMOVE
THE BULLET.
ALL BULLETS HAVE TO BE
RECOVERED AND THEN THEY WOULD
GET MATCHED UP TO WHATEVER
WEAPONS ARE AVAILABLE.
IF THERE'S A BULLET FROM A
WEAPON THAT'S NOT AVAILABLE,
THAT MEANS THERE'S ANOTHER
SHOOTER.
EVEN AS REMOTE THAT MIGHT BE,
THAT'S ONE THING THAT THE
AUTOPSY WILL DO.
BUT THE CAUSE OF DEATH IS NOT
AN ISSUE.
THE AUTOPSY WILL SHOW HOW
CLOSE THE WEAPON WAS AT THE
TIME OF DISCHARGE, WHETHER IT
WAS DISTANT OR RIGHT UP CLOSE,
AND THE AUTOPSY ON THE
PERPETRATOR WILL TELL A LOT,
ON ADAM, WERE THERE ANY DRUGS
IN HIS BODY, HAD HE BEEN
GETTING PSYCHO THERAPEUTIC
DRUGS.
AND THERE'S SOME STUDIES THAT
SHOW SOME CAN MAKE AN AMERICAN
MORE APREGGRESSIVE.
>> AND WHAT DOES HIS BRAIN
LOOK LOOK.
THERE HAVE BEEN QUESTIONS
RAISED OF AUTISM AND
ASPERGER'S, NOTHING TO DO
WITH--
>> AND THE NEWS CONFERENCE NOW
STARTING, LET'S LISTEN TO THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE.
>> GOOD MORNING, WE WANT TO
TAKE A COUPLE OF MINUTES AND
BRING YOU UP-TO-DATE WITH THE
PROGRESS THAT WE'VE MADE IN
THIS INVESTIGATION, WITH THE
CHIEF OF POLICE NEWTOWN, THE
FIELDS OPERATION COMMANDER,
THE STATE POLICE, AND MY
COUNTERPART HERE FROM NEWTOWN
POLICE DEPARTMENT.
AS YOU KNOW, THE VICTIMS HAVE
BEEN POSITIVELY IDENTIFIED BY
THE OFFICER CHIEF STATE
MEDICAL EXAMINER.
THEY'RE STILL IN THE PROCESS
OF DOING SOME OF THEIR WORK
AND AS SOON AS THAT WORK IS
COMPLETED WE WILL BE PREPARED
TO RELEASE IN WRITING TO YOU A
FORMAL LIST OF NAMES, BIRTH
DATES AND INFORMATION.
THERE'S ONE--
WELL, THERE'S A COUPLE OF
MAJOR FACTORS, NUMBER ONE WHEN
WE RELEASE THAT LIST AND ASK
YOU AGAIN AS WE DID YESTERDAY
AT THE REQUEST OF ALL OF THE
FAMILY MEMBERS, THEY HAVE
ASKED FOR YOU TO PLEASE
RESPECT THEIR PRIVACY.
THEY'RE GOING THROUGH, AS I
KNOW YOU UNDERSTAND, A VERY
DIFFICULT AND TRYING TIME.
WE HAVE IN FACT, THE OFFICES
OF THE CHIEF AND COLONEL,
ASSIGNED A TROOPER TO THESE
FOLKS TO HELP TO MAINTAIN THAT
SOLITUDE.
SO, AGAIN, WOULD I ASK YOU AND
I'M PLEADING WITH YOU, AS NOW,
THIS IS AN EXTREMELY HEART
BREAKING, DIFFICULT THING FOR
THESE FOLKS TO ENDURE, TO
PLEASE ABIDE BY THEIR REQUEST.
IN ADDITION, FOR THE TOWNS
PEOPLE IN THE TOWN OF NEWTOWN,
A CRISIS INTERVENTION TEAM
FROM THE YOUNG NEW HAVEN
HOSPITAL HAS BEEN ESTABLISHED
HERE IN THE COMMUNITY AND THEY
CAN BE REACHED VIA TELEPHONE.
THAT TELEPHONE NUMBER IS
203-270-4283.
AND AGAIN, THEY'RE OPEN AND
THEY'RE AVAILABLE TO ANYONE IN
THE COMMUNITY WHO MAY HAVE THE
NEED TO DISCUSS, TO TALK, TO
TALK ABOUT THIS, THIS INCIDENT
IN ITS ENTIRETY.
I HAVE THE ABILITY TO TAKE
SOME QUESTIONS.
I JUST SIMPLY WANT YOU TO
UNDERSTAND THAT WE STILL HAVE
MAJOR CRIME DETECTIVES AND
NEWTOWN DETECTIVES WORKING AT
THE SCENE IN THE SCHOOL.
THAT IS NOT COMPLETED.
THAT PROBABLY WILL NOT BE
COMPLETED FOR AT LEAST ANOTHER
DAY AND A HALF TO TWO DAYS AND
I'M PUTTING A TIME LIMIT ON
IT, IT COULD TAKE LONGER.
AS I EXPLAINED TO YOU IN
PREVIOUS PRESS CONFERENCES,
WE'VE DONE EVERYTHING WE NEED
TO DO TO LITERALLY PEEL BACK
THE ONION, LAYER BY LAYER AND
EXAMINE EVERY CRACK AND
CREVICE OF THAT FACILITY AND
THAT DOES NOT INCLUDE, OR
EXCLUDE, I SHOULD SAY, THE
OUTSIDE OF THE BUILDING.
THE OUTSIDE OF THE BUILDING
ALSO PART OF THE CRIME SCENE
EVERY SINGLE VEHICLE IN THAT
LOT.
SO, IT'S GOING TO BE A LONG,
PAINSTAKING PROCESS, WE
ACTUALLY HAVE THREE TEAMS NOW,
THREE MAJOR CRIME TEAMS IN THE
COMMUNITY, OUR LOCAL PARTNERS
ARE WORKING WITH US AND WE'RE
GOING TO MOVE THAT AND
EXPEDITE THAT ALONG AS QUICKLY
AS POSSIBLE.
WE HAD A MEETING THIS MORNING,
AND THAT WAS THE DELAY WITH
THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE
SCHOOLS, AND SHE WILL BE
HOPEFULLY IN NOT TOO DISTANT
FUTURE UP HERE TO TALK BRIEFLY
ABOUT SOME OF THE ISSUES THAT
SHE HAS ENCOUNTERED.
THE MINUTE, THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER IS DONE AND I MEAN
THAT SINCERELY, THE MINUTE
THAT'S DONE,'S HE COMING HERE
AND WE WILL AGAIN PROVIDE ALL
THE DETAILED INFORMATION OR AS
MUCH DETAILED INFORMATION AS
WE CAN RELATIVE TO THE WORK
THAT HIS OFFICE DID, BOTH
OVERNIGHT AND CONTINUE TO DO
AS WE SPEAK.
AGAIN, AS FAR AS ACTUAL
SPECIFIC QUESTIONS, I'LL TAKE
A FEW, BUT I HAVE TO TELL YOU,
THERE ARE CERTAIN THINGS CARDS
WE'RE HOLDING CLOSE TO OUR
CHEST IN THIS INVESTIGATION
UNTIL, SO NOTHING IS TAKEN OUT
OF CONTEXT AND CONTINUITY OF
INFORMATION THAT WE PROVIDE.
YES, SIR.
>> IT'S REPORTED THERE ARE
OTHER GUNS OTHER THAN WHAT WAS
USED FOUND IN THE SCHOOL.
ARE THOSE REPORTS ACCURATE?
>> NO, THAT'S NOT ACCURATE.
THE WEAPONRY THAT WAS
RECOVERED BY OUR INVESTIGATORS
IN CLOSE PROXIMITY OF THE
DECEASED AND AGAIN, WE'RE
INVESTIGATING THE HISTORY OF
EACH AND EVERY WEAPON.
AND WE WILL KNOW EVERY SINGLE
THING ABOUT THOSE WEAPONS.
I KNOW FOLLOW-UP QUESTIONS,
LEGALLY REGISTERED WHO ARE THE
OWNERS AND SO ON, SO FORTH.
THAT'S DONE BY THE
INVESTIGATOR ASSIGNED TO THAT
TASK.
(INAUDIBLE).
>> WE'RE GOING TO ALLOW, WAIT
FOR THE MEDICAL EXAMINER TO
COME IN AND PROVIDE THE
IDENTITY OF THE SHOOTERS, OF
ALL THE DECEASED IN THIS
INVESTIGATION.
>> AND WRITING, E-MAILS A
ANDDY--
MOTIVE FOR THIS.
>> THAT'S CERTAINLY IS A VERY
GOOD QUESTION.
THE ANSWER I CAN GIVE YOU ON
THAT IS THAT OUR INVESTIGATORS
AT THE CRIME SCENE, THE
SCHOOL, AND SECONDARILY AT THE
SECONDARY CRIME SCENE THAT WE
DISCUSSED WHERE THE LOCATED
DECEASED DID PRODUCE A VERY
GOOD EVIDENCE IN ITS
INVESTIGATION AND OUR
INVESTIGATORS WILL BE ABLE TO
USE AND HOPEFULLY PAINTING THE
COMPLETE PICTURE AS TO HOW ANDM
OCCURRED.
>> AND WOULD YOU
CHARACTERIZE--
>> WE'RE NOT GOING TO NAME THE
EVIDENCE OR TALK ABOUT THE
EVIDENCE, IT'S SIMPLY STATED
AND PART AND PARCEL OF THE
INVESTIGATION AND I DON'T WANT
TO TAKE IT OUT OF THE CONTEXT
OF WHAT'S BEING DONE.
>> AND SHATTERED GLASS AT THE
ENTRANCE OF THE SCHOOL.
>> WE HAVE ESTABLISHED THE
POINT OF ENTRY, IT WAS--
I CAN TELL YOU IT WAS BELIEVED
HE WAS NOT VOLUNTARILY LET
INTO THE SCHOOL AT ALL, THAT
HE FORCED HIS WAY INTO THE
SCHOOL, BUT THAT'S AS FAR AS
WE CAN GO ON THAT.
>> AND BROKEN WINDOWS IN THE
SCHOOL.
>> ARE THERE WHAT?
>> BROKEN WINDOWS AND QUITE
FRANKLY, IF YOU TAKE IT OUT OF
CONTEXT, IT SOUNDS SUSPICIOUS,
BUT AS THE RESCUE CREWS ARRIVE
THE ACTIVE SHOOTING TEAMS
ENTERED THE SCHOOL AND ENTERED
FROM SEVERAL DIFFERENT POINTS
AND IT NECESSITATED FORCING
THEIR WAY IN TO GAIN ACCESS TO
PERFORM THE RESCUE AND SAVE AS
MANY STUDENTS AND FACULTY AS
THEY COULD AND HENCE, LAW
ENFORCEMENT BROKE MANY
WINDOWS.
>> AND WHERE--
>> WHAT'S THAT?
>> (INAUDIBLE).
>> THE OTHER CRIME SCENE, THE
SECONDARY CRIME SCENE AS I
TOLD YOU WAS A CRIME SCENE
DISCOVERED PURSUANT TO THE
INVESTIGATION.
ONCE WE HAD A TENTATIVE
IDENTIFICATION ON THE SUSPECT
WE BEGAN DOING A GREAT DEAL OF
WORK.
AGAIN, PEELING BACK THE ONION
AND EVERYTHING WE COULD FIND
OUT ABOUT THAT SUSPECT AND
INCLUDING AND NOT LIMITED TO
RELATIVES, FRIENDS,
CO-WORKERS, FORMER STUDENTS
AND LOCATION OF RESIDENTS AND
ALL OF THOSE AREAS HAD TO BE,
PEOPLE HAD TO BE INTERVIEWED
AND ALL OF THOSE AREAS HAD TO
BE EXAMINED, HENCE CAUSES TO
DISCOVER THE SECONDARY CRIME
SCENE, A PRIVATE RESIDENCE
WITH A SOLE FEMALE DECEASED.
>> AND WAS--
A MOTIVE OR EXPLANATION AS TO
WHY?
>> TO BE DETERMINED.
THE DETECTIVES WILL CERTAINLY
ANALYZE EVERYTHING AND PUT A
COMPLETE PICTURE TOGETHER OF
THE EVIDENCE THAT THEY DID
OBTAIN.
AND WE'RE HOPEFUL.
WE'RE HOPEFUL THAT IT WILL
PAINT A COMPLETE PICTURE AS TO
HOW AND WHY THIS ENTIRE
INCIDENT, UNFORTUNATE
INCIDENT.
>> AT THE OTHER CRIME SCENE
DID YOU FIND A MAN OR A WOMAN?
>> PARDON ME?
>> THERE WAS A WOMAN SHOT--
>> SHE HAS BEEN TREATED AND
WILL BE INSTRUMENTAL IN THIS
INVESTIGATION, AIM SURE YOU'LL
UNDERSTAND.
THAT I DON'T KNOW, THAT I
DON'T--
>> AND THAT THE SHOOTER IN
THIS CASE APPEARED TO HAVE
RACED INTO THE SCHOOL.
>> FORCIBLY, FORCIBLY INTO THE
SCHOOL.
THAT WOULD BE, THAT WOULD BE
ACCURATE ACCORDING TO
INVESTIGATORS, YES.
>> AND WEAPONS AND--
>> I DON'T, I DON'T WANT TO BE
TOO SPECIFIC.
QUITE FRANKLY, I DON'T KNOW.
SO, I WOULD SIMPLY, I'VE BEEN
ENVELOPED IT WAS FORCIBLY
ENTERED AND WAS NOT ALLOWED TO
ENTER, IF YOU WILL.
>> AND WHAT I'D LIKE TO DO IS
I'D LIKE TO GET THE NEXT
PORTION, IF YOU WILL, TODAY, I
DON'T WANT TO KEEP YOU HERE
ALL DAY AND TRY TO DO THIS AS
EXPEDITIOUSLY AS WE POSSIBLY
CAN AND GET AS MUCH
INFORMATION OUT TO YOU.
WE'D LIKE TO GET THE
SUPERINTENDENT DEFINITELY
WANTS TO COME UP WITH THE TOWN
LEADERS TO DISCUSS CERTAIN
AREAS OF HER RESPONSIBILITY
AND THEN WE CERTAINLY WANT TO
GET THE MEDICAL EXAMINER UP
HERE AND WE'LL DO THAT AS
QUICKLY AS WE POSSIBLY CAN TO
GET THE LIST OF I.D.'S AND THE
INFORMATION OUT TO YOU.
FOR ANY OF THAT ARE NEW HERE
TODAY THE LIEUTENANT AND I
HAVE PUT TOGETHER A WRITTEN
PRESS RELEASE.
WE'LL PROVIDE THOSE TO YOU AT
MY VEHICLE, PLEASE DON'T RUSH
MY VEHICLE, WE HAVE, WE SHOULD
HAVE ENOUGH FOR EVERYONE.
AND IF NOT, WE'LL BRING MORE
NEXT TIME WE COME UP.
IT JUST LAZE OUT THE BASIC
DETAILS OF EVERYTHING LEADING
UP TO TODAY.
ALL RIGHT?
WE WILL, WE WILL TRY, I DON'T
WANT TO GIVE AWE TIME, BUT
WE'LL TRY TO BE BACK HERE, I'M
GOING TO SAY WITHIN THE HOUR,
I'LL MAKE NOTIFICATION TO SOME
OF THAT YOU I CAN THAT WE'RE
ON THE WAY.
ALL RIGHT.
YES, SIR, ONE QUESTION.
>> THE MOTHER OF THE--
(INAUDIBLE)
>>  YOU HAVE TO UNDERSTAND
AFTER THE SHOOTING THAT WE DID
A COMPLETE THOROUGH SEARCH OF
THE ENTIRE AREA, THE
NEIGHBORHOOD, WITH OUR LOCAL
PARTNERS, EVERYTHING,
EVERYTHING WAS EXAMINED AND IF
HE WE FOUND ANYONE IN THE
WOODS CUTTING WOOD, THEY WOULD
BE DETAINED PENDING THE
INVESTIGATION.
THERE WERE NO OTHER ARRESTS
THAT WERE ASSOCIATED WITH
THIS, WITH THIS INVESTIGATION
THAT OCCURRED.
OKAY?
I WAS--
I WOULD HAVE YOU ADDRESS THAT
WITH THE SUPERINTENDENT OF
SCHOOLS, OKAY?
SHE CAN GIVE YOU THAT ANSWER.
WE WILL, WE WILL BE BACK, I
NEED TO GET.
IF I DON'T GET HERE WE'RE
GOING TO BE HERE QUITE SOME
TIME.
AND I KNOW YOU HAVE A LOT OF
QUESTIONS AND I THINK THE
PEOPLE WE'RE COMING HERE TO
SPEAK TO YOU TO ANSWER THE
QUESTIONS AND TAKE A LOT OF
THE MYSTERY OUT OF WHAT WE'VE
BEEN DEALING WITH FOR THE LAST
44 HOURS.
OKAY.
WE WILL, WE WILL BE BACK.
WE WILL BE BACK.
THE NEW INFORMATION TODAY
FROM CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE AND THE
PROMISE OF EVEN MORE
INFORMATION TO COME THUT TKOCOMT
THE DAY AND BRING YOU THAT ON
FOX.
AND WE WANT TO REVIEW A FEW
THINGS WE'VE LEARNED FROM THE
LIEUTENANT MOMENTS AGO.
ONE THING WE LEARNED THIS
MORNING OR HEARD ABOUT THIS
MORNING WAS A CORRECTION TO
WHAT WAS FIRST REPORTED ABOUT
HOW THIS SHOOTER ENTERED THE
SCHOOL.
INITIAL REPORTS POINTED TO THE
FACT THAT HE MIGHT HAVE BEEN
BUZZED IN BY THE FRONT OFFICE.
LIEUTENANT IS TELLING US HOW
WHEN HE ENTERED THE SCHOOL,
THAT WAS NOT A VOLUNTARY
ENTRY.
WE DON'T KNOW EXACTLY HOW HE
FORCED HIS WAY INTO THE
SCHOOL, BUT THAT'S GIVING US A
LITTLE BIT MORE AFTER PICTURE
OF THE CRIME THAT TOOK PLACE
AND ALSO WE REFERRED TO YOU IN
THE PAST THAT SOME CHILDREN
SAW SHATTERED GLASS AS THEY
WERE ON THEIR WAY OUT OF THE
SCHOOL.
AND INITIALLY, AGAIN, TRYING
TO PIECE TOGETHER WHAT
HAPPENED, SOME POINT TODAY
MAYBE THE FACT THAT THAT WAS
BULLETS SHATTERED THE WINDOWS
IN THE SCHOOL.
THE LIEUTENANT ALSO TELLING US
THAT A RESCUE TEAM THAT SHOWED
UP ON SCENE TRIED TO GET IN
THE SCHOOL AND BEST WAY
POSSIBLE AND THAT MAY HAVE
BEEN RESPONSIBLE FOR SOME OF
THE SHATTERED GLASS.
AND ALSO LIVE ON OUR AIR, YOU
SAW ON FOX NEWS, A HELICOPTER
SHOT AROUND THE SCHOOL
YESTERDAY AND IT LOOKED LIKE
INVESTIGATORS WERE HEADED INTO
THE WOODS BEHIND THE SCHOOL.
MUCH LIKE THE WOODS THAT YOU
SEE BEHIND ME RIGHT NOW.
THE SCHOOL ACTUALLY IN THIS
DIRECTION BEHIND ME.
NOW WE'RE LEARNING THAT
INVESTIGATORS WENT TO AROUND
THE SCHOOL AND TALKED TO
PEOPLE AND HEARD FROM THE
LIEUTENANT EVEN IF HE WAS
CHOPPING WOOD, HE WAS GOING TO
TALK TO YOU.
AND FINALLY, A LOT HAS BEEN
SAID ABOUT THE WEAPONS THIS
20-YEAR-OLD HAD AND THE
LIEUTENANT MAKING CLEAR
THEY'RE LOOK INTO THE EACH OF
EACH AND EVERY WEAPON.
NO WORD WHERE THE WEAPONS CAME
FROM AND HOW THIS MINOR WAS
ABLE TO GET HIS HANDS ON THEM.
>> YES, APPARENTLY HE ALSO
SAID, JENNA, AS YOU HEARD,
THAT THEY'VE DEVELOPED VERY
GOOD INFORMATION AS TO THE
CAUSE OF ALL OF THIS SHOOTING.
HE DIDN'T SAY SPECIFICALLY THE
MOTIVE.
HE DIDN'T USE THAT WORD, BUT
HE DID SAY THAT THEY HAVE THAT
INFORMATION AND THAT'S GOING
TO BE--
>> YOU WONDER, JON, YOU
WONDER, JON, IF YOU CAN EVER
EXPLAIN IT, I KNOW WE'LL DO
OUR BEST TO OUR VIEWERS TO TRY
0 GIVE THEM THE FACTS AND I
KNOW THE LIEUTENANT WILL HE AS
WELL, BUT CAN YOU EVER REALLY
EXPLAIN WHAT HAPPENED HERE?
>> THAT'S THE OPEN QUESTION,
CERTAINLY, RIGHT NOW IS A TIME
FOR GRIEVING.
11 YEARS AGO THE NATION WAS
COMFORTED AT ONE OF THE WORST
TIMES IN ITS HISTORY, FRANKLY
NTHE 9/11 ATTACKS AND ONE OF
THE PEOPLE WHO DID A GREAT
DEAL TO HELP HEAL THIS CITY
AND THE NATION ITSELF, THE
FORMER MAYOR OF NEW YORK,
MAYOR RUDY GUILIANI.
HE IS OUR GUEST WITH US NOW
HERE IN THE STUDIO.
SO, WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THE
NATION AT A TIME LIKE THIS?
>> WE JUST SAY HOW SORRY WE
ARE AND WE ALL PRAY TO GOD
THAT THESE FAMILIES CAN GET
THE HELP AND ASSISTANCE AND
THE SENSE OF LOVE THAT THERE
IS FOR THEM ALL OVER THE
COUNTRY AND WE SAW THE
PRESIDENT GIVING THAT TO THEM.
I THINK THE PRESIDENT SPEAKS
FOR THE WHOLE COUNTRY THAT
MOST IMPORTANT THING FOR THEM
TO KNOW NOW THEY'RE NOT ALONE
AND MANY PEOPLE UNFORTUNATELY
HAVE BEEN THROUGH THIS AND
THEY'RE THERE FOR THEM, TRYING
TO HELP THEM THROUGH AND NOT
TO TRY TO ACCOMPLISH TOO MUCH
IN THE FIRST DAY OR TWO.
ON THE POLICE SIDE OF IT, IT
SEEMS THEY'RE DOING EVERYTHING
THEY CAN DO AND HANDLED VERY
PROFESSIONALLY.
AND ON THE OTHER SIDE OF IT
EACH FAMILY WILL BE MOURN
DIFFERENTLY AND GIVEN THE TIME
TO DO IT.
>> ON THE CRIME SIDE, THE
CRIME IS OVER.
WE'VE HEARD SOMETHING ABOABOUT
POSSIBLE MOTIVE AND THE POLICE
THINK THEY MAY KNOW WHAT LED
THIS YOUNG MAN TO SNAP.
TODAY IS THE TIME FOR COMFORT
AND HEALING AND WORRY ABOUT
THE OTHERS DN ADDS.
>> THE REST OF IT WE'RE GOING
TO BE GUESSING AT, HAVING
INVESTIGATED CRIMES NOW FOR 43
YEARS, I CAN TELL YOU THE--
>> A FORMER FEDERAL
PROSECUTOR.
>> THE FIRST THREE OR FOUR
DAYS, HALF THE INFORMATION IS
WRONG, SO YOU CAN SEE
YESTERDAY RIGHT THERE, THE
FIRST REPORT WE HAD THE WRONG
NAME.
WE HAD THE WRONG BROTHER.
AND THEN HE WAS BUZZED INTO
THE SCHOOL.
WELL, HE SHOT HIS WAY INTO THE
SCHOOL AND YOU CAN HAVE A LOT
OF FACTS LIKE THAT THAT CHANGE
AND THERE PROBABLY WILL BE A
EXPLANATI
EXPLANATION.
WHAT THERE WON'T BE AN
UNDERSTANDING OF IT.
THERE WILL PROBABLY
EXPLANATION THAT LIES IN THI