COMPASSION.
BUT WE HAVE PLACED ON OUR
SHOULDERS UNIMAGINABLE PAIN
AND TO MAKE OF THIS WORLD, A
PLACE OF JUSTICE AND PEACE
TRUE FOR OUR PEOPLE,
ESPECIALLY FOR OUR YOUNG.
WE THANK YOU THIS NIGHT FOR
OUR COMMUNITY LEADERS WHO HAVE
WALKED A DARK ROAD HELPING US
FIND A LIGHT.
WE PRAISE YOU FOR MEN AND FOR
WOMEN, IN WHOSE LOVE FOR EACH
OTHER HAVE GIVEN US CHILDREN
THAT WE MIGHT GUIDE AND
ENCOURAGE THEM.
WE SPEAK YOUR WISDOM AS OUR
ADMINISTRATORS AND OUR
EDUCATORS CONTINUE TO TEACH
OUR CHILDREN WAYS THAT WILL
STRENGTHEN THEM TO BE
PRODUCTIVE AND POSITIVE
CITIZENS OF THIS WORLD, TO
ONLY BRING RIGHT AND GOOD, NOT
HARM OR HURT.
AND WE PRAY THAT THIS CULTURE
OF DEATH THAT IS OVERSHADOWING
OUR ENTIRE COUNTRY, ESPECIALLY
NOW, IN THIS, OUR TOWN WILL
SOON BE REPLACED WITH A
CULTURE OF LIFE THAT EMBRACES
EVERY PERSON WITH HUMAN
DIGNITY.
WE HAVE BROUGHT TO YOU TONIGHT
IN YOUR PRAYER THOSE WE HAVE
LOST, THOSE WHOSE HEARTS HAVE
BEEN BROKEN FOREVER, WE BRING
TO YOU 20 NEW STARS IN THE
HEAVENS, 20 NEW SAINTS, 20 NEW
ANGELS, WE BRING TO YOU THOSE
WHO RISK THEIR LIVES FOR US
EVERY DAY, NOT COUNTING THE
COST AND WE BRING TO YOU THOSE
WHO GUIDE, THOSE WHO COUNSEL,
THOSE WHO BLESS AND EMBRACE
THE CONFUSED AND THE BROKEN.
AND NOW, IN THIS PRAYER WE
BRING TO YOU OURSELVES, OUR
BROKENNESS, OUR QUESTIONS, OUR
DOUBTS, OUR ANGER, AND OUR
HEARTS.
AND WE PRAY FOR THE PEACE, THE
HOPE, AND THE RENEWAL OF TRUST
THAT CAN COME ONLY FROM A GOD
WHO FIRST CONCEIVED US IN LOVE
AND PLACES A HAND OF
COMPASSION ON EVERYONE OF OUR
SHOULDERS EVEN IN THIS
CHALLENGING TIME.
SO TONIGHT FOR OUR COMMUNITY,
A COMMUNITY DEEPLY PAINED, WE
ASK YOU TO HEAL THE
BROKENNESS, TO ANSWER OUR
QUESTIONS, TO REPLACE OUR
DOUBTS WITH CERTAINLY, OUR
ANGER WITH PEACE, AND OUR HURT
WITH HEALING.
GOD WE THANK YOU FOR THIS
TOWN.
WE THANK YOU FOR ITS PEOPLE
AND WE THANK YOU FOR THIS
OPPORTUNITY TO STAND TOGETHER
AND NOT TO FALL APART.
AMEN.
...
>> NOW A FINAL BLESSING OF HOPE
THROUGH FAITH JESUS CHRIST IN
THE WORDS OF SAINT JOHN AND ST.
PAUL.
I HEARD A LOUD VOICE FROM THE
THRONE SAYING BE HOLD THE
DWELLING PLACE OF GOD IS WITH
MAN.
HE WILL DWELL WITH THEM AND THEY
WILL BE HIS PEOPLE AND GOD
HIMSELF WILL BE WITH THEM AS
THEIR GOD.
HE WILL WIPE AWAY EVERY TEAR
FROM THEIR EYES AND DEATH SHALL
BE NO MORE.
NEITHER SHALL THERE BE MOURNING
NOR CRYING NOR PAIN ANY MORE,
FOR THE FORMER THINGS HAVE
PASSED AWAY.
HE WHO WAS SEATED ON THE THRONE
SAID, BEHOLD I AM MAKING ALL
THINGS NEW.
NOW MAY THE GRACE OF OUR LORD
JESUS CHRIST AND THE LOVE OF GOD
AND THE COMMUNION OF THE HOLY
SPIRIT BE WITH YOU ALL.
AMEN.
I ASK YOU TO PLEASE TAKE YOUR
SEAT UNTIL I CAN RECEIVE
CONFIRMATION THE PRESIDENT HAS
SAFELY EXITED THE SCHOOL CAMPUS.
I DON'T KNOW WHO THAT
CONFIRMATION IS.
>> THAT IS THE INTERFAITH VIGIL.
ROB MORRIS OF KING LUTHERAN
CHURCH MONSIGNOR WEISE PASTOR OF
THE CATHOLIC CHURCH THERE TO THE
LEFT SIDE.
THE PASTOR ACTUALLY OF THE
CATHOLIC CHURCH IN AN INTERVIEW
HE IS GOING TO HAVE 7 FUNERALS
OVER THE NEXT COUPLE DAYS WHO HE
IS GOING TO PRESIDE OVER THE
CATHOLIC CHURCH STARTING
TOMORROW.
THE MONSIGNOR.
AS ARE MANY OF THOSE PLACES OF
WORSHIP.
THIS WRAPS UP THIS VIGIL AS YOU
PUSH IN A THE 26TH CANDLES.
ED, YOUR THOUGHTS ABOUT THE
PRESIDENT WE TALKED ABOUT HOW IT
WASN'T GOING TO BE A POLICY
ABOUT HEALING IN THIS TOWN.
CLEARLY THERE WAS A MESSAGE HERE
THAT THE NATION IS NOT DOING
ENOUGH TO KEEP KIDS SAFE WHILE
IT WASN'T SPECIFIC IN THE POLICY
PRESCRIPTIONS IT WAS SUGGESTED.
>> IT CERTAINLY WAS.
I WENT BACK TO MY NOTES ONE
ADVISOR TOLD ME BEFORE THE
SPEECH IS THAT IT WAS NOT A
POLICY SYMPOSIUM THAT IT WAS
GOING TO BE A SPEECH THAT WAS
GOING TO BE CONDUCIVE TO THE
VENUE OF A PRAYER VIGIL.
YOU ARE RIGHT.
THERE WASN'T ANY SPECIFIC POLICY
PROPOSAL.
THERE WAS NEVER THE WORDS GUN
CONTROL UTTERED.
THERE WAS NEVER ASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN OR ANYTHING SPECIFIC LIKE
THAT.
MAKE NO MISTAKE HE WAS REFERRING
SPECIFICALLY TO THE IDEA IN THE
WEEKS AHEAD HE WOULD BE TALKING
TO LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS AND
OTHERS ABOUT HOW WE WERE GOING
TO BETTER PROTECT OUR CHILDREN.
WHAT CHOICE DO WE HAVE?
ARE WE PREPARED TO SAY WE ARE
TOO POWERLESS TO DO SOMETHING.
AND THERE WEREN'T SPECIFIC
POLICY PROPOSALS.
HE MADE IT QUITE CLEAR IN THE
WEEKS AHEAD HE IS PLANNING TO
TAKE DRAMATIC ACTION ON THIS
ISSUE.
AS YOU KNOW FROM HEARING FROM
MAYOR BLOOMBERG THEY ARE GOING
TO HOLD THEIR FEET TO THE FIRE.
THAT WILL BE INTERESTING IN THE
DAYS AHEAD.
TWO OTHER THINGS ONE WHEN THE
PRESIDENT WAS READING THE NAMES
AGED THE REPORTERS ARE SAYING
THEY HEARD WEEPING AND HEAVEING
FROM ADULTS WHO ARE HEARING
THOSE CHILDREN'S NAMES THAT IS
SOMETHING THAT STICKS WITH YOU.
WHEN HE INTRODUCED TO THE
PRESIDENT HE TOLD THE GOVERNOR
THAT FRIDAY WAS THE TOUGHEST DAY
OF HIS PRESIDENCY.
I HAVE COVERED HIM FOR FOUR
YEARS NOW THINK BACK TO THE WAR
IN AFGHANISTAN AND THE FINANCIAL
CRISIS DEPLETED THEIR FINANCES
AND THEY HAVE STRUGGLED IN THE
UNEMPLOYED ET CETERA, ET CETERA.
TUCSON, AURORA, WISCONSIN, MANY
OTHER SHOOTINGS.
THE FACT THAT HE SAID FRIDAY WAS
THE WORST DAY OF HIS PRESIDENCY
TELLS YOU THE DEPTH OF THIS
TERRIBLE, TERRIBLE TRAGEDY.
>> AND HENRY, THANK YOU.
IT WAS A POWERFUL SPEECH.
LET'S BRING BACK OUR PANEL STEVE
HAYES, CHARLES KRAUTHAMMER.
>> CHARLES YOUR THOUGHTS?
>> THAT WAS A HIGHLY POLITICAL
SPEECH.
THE BOOK ENDS WERE SIMPLICITY
ITSELF ELEGANT GIVEN HIS
UNDERSTANDING OF THE GRIEF AND
SORT OF EXTENDING HIS
CONDOLENCES TO THE FAMILY AND
THE NATION.
THE MIDDLE PART OF THAT SPEECH
WAS A DETERMINATION OF THIS
PRESIDE
PRESIDENT>> HE WROTE A LOT OF
THIS ON HIS OWN.
HE DIDN'T HAVE TO GO THROUGH
INTERAGENCY CONSIDERATION THIS
IS HIS COMMITMENT.
IT SOUNDED LIKE HE'S GOING TO DO
SOMETHING.
IT'S ALMOST LIKE LBJ AFTER
KENNEDY IS KILLED AND HE SAID I
AM GOING TO BE THE CIVIL RIGHTS
I AM GOING TO COMPLETE THE CIVIL
RIGHTS.
I HOPE IT ISN'T ONLY ABOUT GUN
CONTROL BUT I THINK HE WAS
ANNOUNCING SOMETHING SERIOUS WAS
GOING TO HAPPEN AND IT WOULD
COME TO HIM PERSONALLY.
>> WE ARE NOT GOING TO BE
POWERLESS IN THE FACE OF THIS
KARNAGE.
WHAT WAS DISTURBING TO ME OUT OF
THIS WHICH OTHERWISE WAS POETIC
SPEECH HE WAS GOING TO ACT
UNILATER
UNILATERALLY.
MAY BE WRONG THERE WEREN'T A LOT
OF DETAILS IN THERE BUT THE
ENERGY WILL COME OUT OF THE
WHITE HOUSE.
UNITE THIS COUNTRY AROUND THIS
RATHER THAN DIVIDE THE COUNTRY
THESE ARE EXPLOSIVE ISSUES WE
ARE TALKING ABOUT.
YOU HAVE TO TAKE OF THE
HEATED WATERS AND PUT IT IN
CONSIDERATION YOU HAVE TO BRING
PARTIES TO THE TABLE THAT AREN'T
JUST THE WHITE HOUSE.
YOU HAVE TO DO IT FROM THE GET
GO.
>> ARE WE DOING ENOUGH TO KEEP
OUR CHILDREN SAFE.
THE ANSWER IS NO.
I WILL BE INTERESTED TO FIND OUR
WHAT IT IS LIKE FOR THE SPEECH.
IT IS POSSIBLE ED HENRY SEES IT
ONE THING AND SAW FAMILIES AND
HEARD FROM THEM MAYBE THIS WAS
THE TYPE OF THING THEY WANTED TO
HEAR.
MAYBE THEY WANTED THE PRESIDENT
TO STEP UP AND SAY ENOUGH IS
ENOUGH.
WE CAN'T GO ON LIKE THIS ANY
MORE.
I DIDN'T TAKE AWAY HE WAS GOING
TO ACT UNILATERALLY.
HE DON'T KNOW IF IT WILL BE JUST
ON GUNS OR MENTAL ILLNESS.
>> I THINK IT IS A TURNING
POINT.
HE MADE UNMISTAKABLY CLEAR WE
HAVE TO MAKE A CHANGE WE CAN'T
TOLERATE THIS ANY MORE THE
TRAGEDIES MUST END.
THOSE ARE NOT THINGS YOU CAN'T
GO BACK FROM.
YOU HAVE TO MOVE FORWARD.
I THOUGHT HE SPOKE EFFECTIVELY
FIRST AS A FATHER AND THEN AS A
LEADER.
I SUSPECT I WON'T AGREE WITH
SOME OF HIS POLICY BUT IT WAS AN
EFFECTIVE POWERFUL SPEECH.
>> IT WAS POWERFUL.
IT WAS A POWERFUL TIME TO HEAR
THE KID'S NAMES READ AT THE END
AND THE SOBBING IN THAT ROOM.
JUST WRAPPED IT UP.
THAT CONCLUDES FOX NEWS CHANNEL
SPECIAL COVERAGE OF THE PRAYER
SERVICE IN NEW TOWN CONNECTICUT.
I AM BRET BAIER IN WASHINGTON.
SPECIAL REPORT CONTINUES
TOMORROW 6:00 P.M. EASTERN.
WE WILL HAVE THIS COVERED
JUSTICE WITH JUDGE JANEANE IS
LIVE AFTER THE BREAK.
>> YOU WERE THE DIRECTOR OF
SECURITY FOR THE BOARD OF
EDUCATION WHICH INCLUDED A HIGH
SCHOOL WHERE THE SHOOTER
ATTENDED AS WELL AS PART OF THE
SAME SCHOOL DISTRICT WHERE THESE
CHILDREN, THESE INNOCENT
CHILDREN WERE MURDERED ALONG
WITH MANY OF THEIR TEACHERS.
>> YES.
>> AS DIRECTOR OF SECURITY YOU
HAD OCCASION TO MEET AND
INTERACT WITH MANY STUDENTS.
>> YES, MOST OF THEM.
>> AND YOU DID MEET I BELIEVE
SEVERAL YEARS AGO THE SHOOTER IN
THIS CASE ADAM LANZA.
WHAT WERE YOUR IMPRESSIONS OF
HIM?
>> I BELIEVE I FIRST MET HIM
THROUGH THE MIDDLE SCHOOL PRIOR
TO HIM COMING INTO THE HIGH
SCHOOL.
MY IMPRESSIONS OF HIM WERE VERY
HIGH IN THE BEGINNING.
HE WAS A YOUNG MAN NOT UNLIKE
OTHER YOUNG MEN BUT WITH A FEW
DISORDERS THAT HAD TO BE
ADDRESSED.
>> WHAT KIND OF DISORDERS?
>> ASBURGERS IS OUT THERE.
HE WAS WITHDRAWN AND HAD
DIFFICULTY INTERACTING WITH
OTHER STUDENTS.
>> RICHARD, WHEN YOU SAY
ASBERGERS IS OUT THERE, DID YOU
KNOW THAT AT THE TIME?
HOW OLD WAS HE WHEN YOU FIRST
MET HIM?
DO YOU REMEMBER?
>> 13SHGS 14 YEARS OLD IN MIDDLE
SCHOOL.
>> DID ANY ONE MENTION THAT HE
WAS SUFFERING FROM THAT ISSUE?
>> IT WOULD HAVE BEEN IN THE
HIGH SCHOOL WHEN HE WAS COMING
INTO HIGH SCHOOL.
>> YOU SAID IT WAS REPORTED THAT
YOU WERE A TECH CLUB ADVISOR.
TELL US ABOUT THAT.
>> YEAH, THE SCHOOL HAS CLUBS.
I RAN THE TECH CLUB AS THE
ADVISOR OF THAT CLUB.
HE WAS PART OF THAT CLUB.
IT WAS A LARGE CLUB WE HAD IN
SCHOOL.
>> AND WHAT DID PEOPLE DO IN THE
TECH CLUB?
>> VIDEO PRODUCTIONS OF EVERY
KIND, BASKETBALL GAMES, FOOTBALL
GAMES, SPORTS, GRADUATIONS,
EVENTS IN TOWN, BIT OF RADIO
STATION AS WELL.
>> SO THE KIDS IN THIS CLUB --
>> I AM SORRY, RICHARD.
>> THAT'S OKAY.
>> THESE KIDS DIDN'T TIN THE CLB
WERE TECH -- TECHY KIDS.
>> HOW WOULD YOU DESCRIBE ADAM
IN PARTICULAR?
>> HIGH-TECH -- HIGH
INTELLECTUAL TECHY WHO LOVED TO
BE INVOLVED IN THE VIDEO
PRODUCTIONS, LOVED TO BE
INVOLVED IN ALL OF THE ASPECTS
THAT ENTAILED CAMERA WORK,
AUDIO, BUT THE CLUB ITSELF WAS
WAS A PLACE TO BE LONG.
>> DID HE NEED THAT?
>> YES, HE DEFINITELY NEEDED
THAT DESPERATELY.
>> WHY DO YOU SAY THAT?
>> WELL, IT GOES BACK TO SAYING
THAT HE WAS WITHDRAWN MOST OF
THE TIME, HE WAS VERY QUIET.
IN HIS FRESHMAN YEAR HE WAS VERY
SMALL IN SIZE AND HE HAD A LOT
OF FEAR COMING INTO THE HIGH
SCHOOL AND INTERACTING WITH
OTHER STUDENTS.
>> BUT DID HE HAVE A REASON TO
BE FEARFUL OF THE OTHER
STUDENTS?
WAS HE PICKED ON?
>> NOT REALLY, NO.
NO.
NOT REALLY.
NEWTOWN SYSTEM ITSELF IS A VERY,
VERY LOVING CARING SCHOOL.
THE ADMINISTRATORS, THE
TEACHERS, MOST OF THE STUDENTS
USUALLY ADOPT KIDS YOUNGER THAN
THEM.
NO, THERE WASN'T.
>> ALL RIGHT.
RICHARD DID YOU HAVE OCCASION TO
MEET HIS MOTHER DURING THE TIME
THAT HE WAS IN SCHOOL, NANCY
LANZA?
>> YES, OFTEN.
>> TELL US ABOUT HER.
>> SHE WAS A GREAT PERSON.
I LIKED HER VERY, VERY MUCH.
SHE WAS THE TYPE OF PARENT WHO
INTERACTED WITH HER CHILDREN,
WAS DEEPLY INVOLVED IN THE
EDUCATIONAL PROCESS.
FRIENDS WERE PROBABLY CHOSEN
WELL.
THE ACTIVITIES SHE WAS INVOLVED
IN ALL OF THE TIME.
>> HOW DID SEE AHE AND HER SON
INTERACT?
>> TOUGH TO SAY.
QUITE WELL.
THERE WAS A DIFFERENCE BETWEEN
TWOT BOYS.
ONE WAS OUT GOING AND  ENERGETI
ADAM WAS WITHDRAWN AND SHY.
THE IDEA WAS TO INJECT HIM INTO
AN ENVIRONMENT WHERE HE WOULD
THRIVE AND MAYBE GROW AND COME
OUT OF HIS WORLD.
>> WERE YOU SURPRISED WHEN YOU
HEARD ALL OF THIS?
>> SHOCKED.
I AM STILL SHOCKED.
>> WHY?
>> THIS IS A BOY WHO WAS MORE
LIKELY A VICTIM WHICH IS WHY I
WOULD WATCH HIM VERY CLOSELY
RATHER THAN BE THE PERSON WHO
VICTIMIZED.
I AM SHOCKED.
>> FRIDAY MORNING JUST BLEW ME
AWAY.
I WAS BUSY WITH WORK AND I FIST
RECEIVED A TEXT FROM MY OWN SON
WHO ATTENDED THE SCHOOL SYSTEMS.
I REALLY I DO BELIEVE THIS COULD
BE POSSIBLE.
>> ARE YOU SURPRISED THE MOM HAD
SO MANY GUNS?
>> I AM SHOCKED.
I AM SURPRISED SHE HAD THAT MANY
GUNS.
CAUSED ME TO REALLY RETHINK
KEEPING ME UP AT NIGHT WONDERING
WHY I WOULD NOT HAVE ENVISIONED
HER NOT ONLY TO HAVE GUNS BUT
THE TYPE OF GUNS.
>> WE THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
SHARING YOUR INSIGHT ON THE
SHOOTER AND HIS MOTHER.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US THIS
EVENING.
>> THANK YOU, JUDGE.
>> COMING UP TOMORROW MORNING
MILLIONS OF CHILDREN WILL GO
BACK TO SCHOOL.
WILL THEY EVEN BE SAFE?
CAN SOMETHING LIKE THIS HAPPEN
AGAIN?
LATER THEY SAY TIME HEALS ALL
WOUNDS, BUT HOW LONG WILL IT
TAKE TO HEAL AFTER A TRAGEDY
LIKE THIS.
(INAUDIBLE)
>> TOMORROW MORNING MILLIONS OF
CHILDREN ACROSS AMERICA HEAD
BACK TO SCHOOL.
THEIR PARENTS ARE NOW FORCED TO
WONDER, IS MY CHILD SAFE?
WITH ME IS FORMER NYPD DETECTIVE
AND SCHOOL SAFETY EXPERT.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US,
HARRY.
WE KNOW THE SANDY HOOK SCHOOL
SYSTEM THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
PARTICULAR HAD MEASURES IN PLACE
FOR SAFETY, AND IT IS OBVIOUS TO
STOP THIS CRAZED INDIVIDUAL.
HE IS EVIL.
HE DID THE DEVIL'S WORK.
WHAT CAN WE DO IN SCHOOLS TO
PROTECT OUR CHILDREN?
>> THEY DID HAVE SOME PLAN IN
THE SCHOOL.
WE COULD PROBABLY TWEAK THAT,
THOUGH.
>> HOW?
>> APPARENTLY THE SHOOTER GOT IN
THROUGH THE GLASS DOOR.
WHAT HAPPENS IS HE SHOT THE
GLASS DOOR OUT AND WENT INSIDE.
THE CLASS ITSELF WASN'T -- WAS
VERY EASILY PENETRATED.
HE WAS ABLE TO ACCESS THE
SCHOOL.
SO THERE'S A COUPLE DIFFERENT
THINGS WE CAN DO.
>> WHAT?
>> SOMETHING SIMPLE LIKE PUT THE
BARS ON THE DOORS.
>> PEOPLE SAY, HARRY THAT THAT'S
INTIMIDATING.
YOU DON'T WANT METAL DETECTORS
YOU DON'T WANT A COP WITH A GUN.
NOW YOU ARE TALKING BARS.
YOU BELIEVE THIS IS SOMETHING WE
NEED TO DO?
>> I THINK THAT THE LOCK DOWN IS
PROBABLY THE ANSWER.
>> DESCRIBE A LOCK DOWN.
>> YOU DO WITH YOUR EMERGENCY
ACTION PLAN.
IT IS BASICALLY LOCKING DOWN THE
SCHOOL WHICH THEY TRIED TO DO.
THEY LOCKED ALL OF THE DOORS.
>> BUT THE SHOOTER IS IN THE
SCHOOL.
RIGHT, EXACTLY.
THE SHOOTER GOT INTO THE SCHOOL.
IF THEY HAD SOME KIND OF BARS ON
THAT DOOR MAYBE THE SHOOTER
COULD NOT HAVE GOTTEN TO THE
SCHOOL.
>> SO LET'S ACCOUPLE THAT THERE
IS THIS AS YOU CALL SAFETY OR
EMERGENCY ACTION PLAN.
THAT MEANS THAT WE HAVE TO TRAIN
THE TEACHERS AND EFSHL ELSE.
IS THIS EXPENSIVE?
WHO PAYS FOR IT IN A WORLD WHERE
THE END OF THE FISCAL CLIFF, HOW
DIFFICULT IS IT?
>> WE KNOW THAT SCHOOLS AREN'T
GOING TO PUT 50,000 DOLLARS INTO
A SECURITY UPGRADE.
SOMETHING LIKE THIS IS EASY TO
DO.
IT IS A LITTLE SCHOOLING.
YOU CAN BASICALLY GET A HANDYMAN
TO DO SOME OF THE WORK TO THE
WINDOWS AND TO THE DOORS AND YOU
WILL HAVE A HE CSECURE SCHOOL.
WHAT WE NEED TO DO IS HAVE SOME
TYPE OF AN ALARM WHERE THEY KNOW
IT IS TIME FOR THE LOCK DOWN.
>> EVERYBODY HEARD WHAT WAS
GOING ON.
>> WHAT SHOULD PARENTS DO
TOMORROW MORNING SHOULD THEY
CALL THEIR SCHOOL AND SAY HEY
WHAT IS THE SAFETY PLAN FOR MY
CHILD?
>> THAT IS SOMETHING THEY SHOULD
DEFINITELY DO.
I SUGGEST PARENTS CALL THE
SCHOOL AND ASK THEM DO YOU HAVE
AN EMERGENCY ACTION PLAN IN
EFFECT IN THE SCHOOL?
IF NOT, WHY?
AND IF NOT, WHEN?
GET TOGETHER WITH THE PTA, THEN
YOU CAN ALL GET TOGETHER TALK
WITH THE SCHOOL OFF FIFSH SHALLS
AND POLICE AND PUT AN EMERGENCY
ACTION PLAN TOGETHER.
LOCK DOWN IS VERY COST
EFFECTIVE.
>> WHAT ABOUT CHILDREN?
WHEN YOU SAY THAT WE HEARD ABOUT
THE DRILLS THESE CHILDREN
BEFORE, I USE TO DO HIDE UNDER
THE DESK.
MY KIDS WILL SAY THAT'S WHERE
THEY WERE WRITTEN ON THE SILK
TABLETS.
TODAY THE DRILL IS
SIMPLY TO GO OUT OF THE SCHOOL?
HOW DO YOU PREPARE LITTLE KIDS
WITHOUT SCARING THEM?
>> FOR AN ACTIVE SHOOTER YOU
DON'T WANT THE KIDS RUNNING OUT
OF SCHOOL.
THEY CAN RUN INTO THE ACTIVE
SHOOTER.
YOU WANT TO BE ABLE TO LOCK DOWN
THE CLASSROOM.
IF YOU CAN LOCK DOWN THE
CLASSROOM, GET THE CHILDREN DOWN
ON THE FLOOR, TAKE THEIR DESKS
LAY THEM OVER GET BEHIND THE
DESKS LOCK THE DOOR SO THE
SHOOTER DOESN'T GAIN ACCESS TO
THAT.
THE FIRST TWO OR THREE MINUTES
OF AN ACTIVE SHOOTER INCIDENT IS
THE DEADLIEST.
WHAT WE WANT TO DO IS WE WANT TO
SLOW HIM DOWN SO THAT IF WE SLOW
HIM DOWN THE POLICE CAN RESPOND
AND THEN THE POLICE CAN DEAL
WITH HIM.
>> VERY QUICKLY, YOU WERE A
DETECTIVE, HOMICIDE DETECTIVE AT
NYPD.
THESE GUNS WE WERE HEARING ABOUT
THE GLOCH THE BUSHMASTER A LOT
OF VIEWERS DON'T KNOW WHAT THEY
ARE CAPABLE OF.
A SEMIAUTOMATIC THEY ARE TALKING
ABOUT 30 ROUNDS TO A CLIP.
HOW QUICKLY CAN THAT GO OFF?
>> YOU HAVE THE BUSHMASTER.
>> WHICH IS RIGHT ON THE SCREEN
RIGHT THERE.
>> YOU HAVE THE 223 OR 2.56
ROUND MILITARY ROUND.
YOU CAN EMPTY A 30 ROUND CLIP IN
LESS THAN 15 SECONDS IF YOU ARE
REALLY TRAINED TO DO THAT.
>> THAT IS SCARY.
>> THEY SAID THERE WERE HUNDREDS
OF ROUNDS.
OBVIOUSLY 30 ROUND CLIP HUNDREDS
OF ROUNDS THAT MEANS HE WAS
RELOADING.
>> IN ALL CASES THIS QUICK, BAM,
BAM.
>> APPRECIATE IT.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR EXPERTISE.
DO WE SPEND TOO MUCH TIME TRYING
TO UNDERSTAND WHAT TO ME IS
SIMPLY AND PURELY EVIL?
AND LATER, DOES FAITH, RELIGION
AND BELIEF IN GOD HOLD A KEY TO
HEALING?
HAVE A GOOD NIGHT.
RE YOU GO. YOU, TOO.
I'M GOING TO DREAM
ABOUT THAT STEAK.
ABOUT THAT TIRAMISU.
WHAT A NIGHT, HUH?
BUT, UM, CAN THE TEST DRIVE
BE OVER NOW?
HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A PASSAT.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN, $0 DUE AT SIGNING,
$0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
CAN YOU START THE DAY
THE WAY YOU WANT?
CAN ORENCIA HELP?
COULD YOUR "I WANT"
BECOME "I CAN"?
TALK TO YOUDOCTOR.
ORENCIA REDUCES
MANY RA SYMPTOMS
LIKE PAIN, MORNING STIFFNESS
AND PROGRESSION
OF JOINT DAMAGE.
IT'S HELPED NEW RA PATIENTS
AND THOSE NOT HELPED ENOUGH
BY OTHER TREATMENTS.
DO NOT TAKE ORENCIA
WITH ANOTHER BIOLOGIC MEDICINE
FOR RA
DUE TO AN INCREASED RISK
OF SERIOUS INFECTION.
SERIOUS SIDE EFFECTS CAN OCCUR
INCLUDING FATAL INFECTIONS.
CASES OF LYMPHOMA AND
LUNG CANCER HAVE BEEN REPORTED.
DUE TO AN INCREASED RISK
OF SERIOUS INFECTION.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU ARE
PRONE TO OR HAVE ANY INFECTION
LIKE AN OPEN SORE OR THE FLU
OR A HISTORY OF COPD,
CHRONIC LUNG DISEASE.
ORENCIA MAY WORSEN YOUR COPD.
[ Male Announcer ]
NOW LEARN ABOUT A PROGRAM
COMMITTED TO YOU
AND COPAY ASSISTANCE THAT CAN
REDUCE MONTHLY ORENCIA
OUT-OF-POCKET
DRUG COST TO $5.
IF YOU'RE
NOT SATISFIED
AFTER 6 MONTHS,
YOU GET
THAT MONEY BACK.
CALL 1-800-ORENCIA.
TO TELL REAL PEOPLE ABOUT
OUR NEW 15 UNDER $15 MENU.
OH MY GOODNESS!
OH MY GOSH,
THIS LOOKS AMAZING!
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR NEW MAINE STAYS!
15ENTREES UNDER $15,
SEAFOOD, CHICKEN AND MORE!
OOTHE TILAPIAWITH ROASTEDEGETAB!
I'M ACTUALLY LOOKING AT
THE WO GRILLED CHICKEN
WITH PORTOBELLO WINE SAUCE.
AT PORK CHOP
WAS GREAT!
NO MORE
FAST FOOD FRIDAY'S!
WE'RE GOING TO GO
TO RED LOBSTER.
YEP.
[ Male Announcer ]
COME TRY OUR NEW MENU
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
SALAD, SANDWICHES, AND MORE.
>> LIVE FROM AMERICA'S NEWS
HEADQUARTERS.
FOLLOWING SECRETARY OF STATE
HILLARY CLINTON RECOVERING AT
HOME FAINTING LAST WEEK AND
RECOVERING FROM A CONCUSSION.
SHE WAS SCHEDULED TO TESTIFY
BEFORE CONGRESSIONAL PANELS
THURSDAY LOOKING INTO THE ATTACK
ON THE U.S. CONSULATE IN
BENGHAZI LIBYA.
THE DOCTORS ADVISED HER TO
CANCEL ALL WORK EVENTS RIGHT
NOW.
TH
STATE OFFICIALS WILL TESTIFY IN
HER PLACE.
GROWING MISERY IN THE
PHILIPPINES AS THE DEATH TOLL
HAS GROWN MORE THAN 1,000 FROM A
TYPHOON THAT DEVASTATED TOWNS.
THAT NUMBER IS EXPECTED TO RISE
SHARPLY.
A MASSIVE SEARCH FOR 844 PEOPLE
STILL MISSING IS SET TO CONTINUE
INTO THE YEAR.
ARMY TROOPS AND GOVERNMENT
PERSONNEL CELEBRATING CHRISTMAS
IN ORDER TO HELP OUT.
NOW BACK TO JUSTICE JUDGE
JANEANE FROM NEWTOWN
CONNECTICUT.
>> THE PERSON THAT CHOOSE TO ACT
THIS WAY WAS ACTING WITH A GOD
GIVEN RIGHT HE WAS GIVEN BY GOD
THAT HAS GIVEN ALL OF US TO ACT
AND CHOOSE WHATEVER WE WANT.
GOD CAN'T TAKE THAT AWAY FROM
US.
>> THE TOWN STRUGGLES TO COME TO
GRIPS WITH THE UNIMAGINABLE.
THE QUESTION REALLY IS HOW WILL
WE EVEN BEGIN TO HEAL.
WITH ME CLINICAL PSYCHOLOGIST
AUTHOR OF INSIDE THE CRIMINAL
MIND AND PSYCHOLOGIST DR. ROBY
LUDWIG.
>> YOU SAW THAT IT IS
HEARTBREAKING THE FATHER OF A
6-YEAR-OLD THWHO BASICALLY FOR
GIVES HE IS NOT ANGRY.
HOW DOES A PARENTS DO THAT?
>> HE WASNHASN'T GOTTEN IN TOUC
WITH HIS ANGER.
IT IS SOMETHING HE WILL HAVE TO
DEAL WITH.
HIS WHOLE LIFE WAS TURNED UPSIDE
DOWN.
HIS DAUGHTER'S LIFE WAS ROBBED
FROM HER.
O
SO OF COURSE THERE'S ANGER.
THERE'S A HEALTHY COMPONENT.
IF YOU GET STUCK IN THE ANGER
THAT IS WHEN IT IS NOT HEALTHY.
YOU CAN HEAR THE FATHER'S
INSTINCTS ARE REALLY GOOD.
HE'S KEEPING HIS DAUGHTER'S
MEMORY ALIVE MAKING THE MEMORY
VIVID FOR THE WHOLE WORLD TO
EXPERIENCE.
THAT'S THE FIRST HEALTHY STEP
MANY OF THE PARENTS ARE GOING TO
NEED TO DO.
>> WHEN I WAS READING ABOUT THE
CHILDREN, THERE IS ONE OF THE
CHILDREN NOAH WHO IS GOING TO BE
BURIED TOMORROW.
HE HAS A TWIN SIBLING.
SHE WAS IN ANOTHER CLASSROOM.
HOW DOES SHE AT THIS YOUNG AGE,
SHE WON'T REALLY COMPLETELY
UNDERSTAND IT, BUT AT SOME POINT
WILL SHE HAVE WHAT'S CALLED
SURVIVOR'S GUILT?
>> WE DON'T HAVE THE ANSWERS TO
EVERYTHING THAT HAPPENS IN LIFE.
WE DON'T KNOW WHY CHILDRERTAIN E
SURVIVE AND CERTAIN PEOPLE
DON'T.
PERHAPS HER ROLE CAN BE IN
TRYING TO MAKE THIS A POSITIVE
FOR HERSELF.
GIVE HER BROTHER'S LIFE SOME
MEANING.
WHO KNOWS, MAYBE SHE WILL END UP
BEING A DEFENSE ATTORNEY ONE
DAY.
>> MAYBE A PROSECUTOR.
>> I TACHANGE MY STATEMENT.
>> DOCTOR, YOU ARE VERY FAMILIAR
WITH THE CRIMINAL ELEMENTS WHO
BASICALLY REFUSES TO BE CAUGHT
IN A TRAP OF LABELLING THESE
PEOPLE WHO ARE KILLING UNDER THE
GOOIDZ OF A MENTAL ILLNESS.
>> THE TALK ABOUT AUTISM AND THE
SHOOTER LACKING SOCIAL SKILLS.
DO YOU REALIZE EVERY ONE OF
THESE SHOOTERS HAS BEEN
DESCRIBED AS A LOANER AND WITH
DRAWN.
YOU KNOW WHY THAT IS?
BECAUSE THESE ARE PEOPLE WHO
DON'T WANT OTHERS TO KNOW THEM.
THESE ARE PEOPLE WHO ARE
SECRETIVE.
THESE ARE PEOPLE WHO HAVE A LOT
GOING ON IN THEIR MINDS THAT
THEY WILL NOT ANNOUNCE TO
OTHERS.
THEY SIMPLY DON'T HAVE SOCIAL
SKILLS BECAUSE THEY DON'T CARE
ABOUT SOCIAL SKILLS.
THEIR VIEW OF LIFE IS THEY ARE
THE HUB OF THE WHEEL EVERYTHING
MUST REVOLVE AROUND IT.
WE PUT LABELS ON TRYING TO
EXPLAIN THE UNEXPLAINABLE AND
THERE BY CREATE MORE EXCUSES.
>> DOCTOR AS SOMEONE WHO TRIED A
LOT OF CRIMINAL CASES MURDER
CHASES INSANITY DEFENSES I NEVER
THOUGHT THE ISSUE OF INSANITY
WHICH PEOPLE WILL SURELY COME
UPON IN THE NEAR FUTURE AS IT
RELATES TO THIS CASE HAS
ANYTHING TO DO WITH THE FACT OF
WHAT WAS DONE.
AND SO THE LABELLING OF
ASPERGER'S WHICH I HAVE SEEN IT
USED IN OTHER HOMICIDE CASES IS
ALMOST AN EXCUSE.
PEOPLE SAY OH BUT HE WAS SMART.
THAT'S ALMOST AN EXCUSE AS WELL.
>> THE FACT THAT THE PERPETRATOR
WAS SMART MAKES FOR A WONDER RL
COVER.
IF YOU ARE SMART, A BRAINIAC I
BELIEVE HE WAS CALLED THAT MAKES
IT EASIER TO GET A PASS FOR
OTHERS TO FOCUS ON HOW BRIGHT
THE PERSON IS.
THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO SAID TO ME
TO KILL SOMEBODY YOU HAVE TO BE
INSANE.
YOU HAVE TO LOOK AT THE FACTS OF
THE CASE.
HOW THE SHOOTINGS WERE COMMITTED
HOW PURPOSEFUL, HOW RATIONAL AND
DELIBERATE BRAT THEY WERE.
>> SPINNING OFF OF IT YOU HAVE A
GUY WHO SHOOTS HIS OWN MOTHER IN
THE FACE, SHOOTS HER FOUR TIMES.
WHAT IS HE SO ANGRY ABOUT?
>> WE DON'T KNOW.
BUT CLEARLY THERE WAS A
CONTENTIOUS RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN
HIM AND HIS MOTHER.
>> WE HEARD ABOUT FROM THE
TEACHER, I BELIEVE FOUR YEARS
BACK MAYBE THREE YEARS BACK IS
THE MOTHER CARED ABOUT HIM AND
CARED ABOUT HIM.
>> SHE MAY HAVE.
INTERPERSONAL RELATIONSHIPS
BETWEEN A MOTHER AND A CHILD CAN
BE VERY CONFLICTED.
PERHAPS HER SON GOT WORSE AS
TIME WENT ON.
HE WAS OUT OF CONTROL.
IT SOUNDS LIKE FOR SOME REASON
THEY WERE TOO ISOLATED THAT THE
MOTHER AND SON HAD TOO MUCH TIME
TOGETHER.
I DON'T KNOW HOW MUCH OUTSIDE
INTERVENTION SHE ASKED FOR.
SOUNDS LIKE SHE HOME SCHOOLED
HIM.
>> I HAVE A FEW SECONDS BEFORE
WE GO TO BREAK.
THE IDEA OF A MOTHER KNOWING HER
SON HAD PROBLEMS AND THEN TAKING
HIM TO A GUN RANGE, HAVING THESE
HIGH POWERED WEAPONS AND CLIPS
OBVIOUSLY.
A GLOCK AND A BUSHMASTER WHICH
IS LIKE AN AR 15 ASSAULT RIFLE.
WHAT WAS SHE THINKING?
>> YOU DON'T HAVE TO HAVE A
PH.D. TO SAY IT DOESN'T SOUND
LIKE A GOOD IDEA.
EVEN IF SHE SOUGHT HELP FOR HIM,
WE DON'T KNOW IF SHE DID OR NOT.
IT'S HARD TO GET HELP FOR A KID
LIKE THIS, TO DE CATAIN A KID T
GET ADEQUATE TREATMENT IT IS
VERY HARD IN THE YEAR 2012 TO DO
THAT.
>> DOCTOR, BOTH OF YOU STAY WITH
US.
>>> COMING UP THIS WEEK THE
BURIALS WILL START.
HOW CAN A PARENT POSSIBLY HEAL
FROM SUCH A TRAUMATIC EVENT.
LATER THE ROLE OF RELIGION AND
FAITH AND HEALING IN THIS
PROCESS.
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
YOU'LL ALSO CARE ABOUT
OUR NEW OFFER.
YOU GET ACCESS TO NURSES WHO
CAN HELP WITH YOUR QUESONS.
AND YOUR LOVED ONE CAN GE
EXELON PATCH FREE FOR 30 DAYS.
IF THE DOCTOR FEELS
IT'S RIGHT FOR THEM.
IT CANNOCHANGE
HOW THE DIASE PROGRESSES.
HOSPITALIZATION
AND RARELY ATH
HAVE BEEN REPORTED IN PATIENTS
WHO WORE MORE THAN ONE PATCH
AT A TIME.
THE MOST COMMON SIDE EFFECTS
OF EXELON PATCH
ARE NAUSEA, VOMITING,
AND DIARRHEA.
THE LIKELIHOOD AND SEVERITY
OF THESE SIDE EFFECTS
MAY INCREASE
AS THE DOSE INCREASES.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
LOSS OF APPETITE OR WEIGHT.
PATIENTS WHO WEIGH
LESS THAN 110 POUNDS
MAY EXPERIENCE
MORE SIDE EFFECTS.
PEOPLE AT RISK
FOR STOMACH ULCERS
WHO TAKE CERTAIN
OTHER MEDICINES
SHOULD TALK TO THEIR DOCTOR
BECAUSE SERIOUS
STOMACH PROBLEMS
SUCH AS BLEEDING MAY WORSEN.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
SLOW HEART RATE.
THIRTY DAYS OF EXELON PATCH
FREE FOR YOUR LOVED ONE.
ACCESS TO TRAINED NURSES
FOR YOU.
CALL 1-855-999-1399
OR VISIT EXELONPATCHOFFER2.COM.
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
DAVINO.
>> SHE HEARD EVERYTHING THE
SHOTS AND THE DOORS SLAMMING AND
PEOPLE YELLING.
SHE JUST WANTED TO COME HOME.
HER HEART WAS RACING.
SHE WAS SCARED.
>> THE FIRST FUNERAL FOR ONE OF
THE YOUNG ANGELS KILLED IN THE
SHOOTING IS SET FOR TOMORROW.
6-YEAR-OLD NOAH POZNER WILL BE
LAID TO REST IN FAIRFIELD,
CONNECTICUT.
WITH ME IS GRIEF COUNSELOR
ROBINWOODMAN AND DR. SAM NOW IS
STILL WITH US.
TALK TO ME ABOUT THIS WEEK
PARENTS BAUURYING THEIR CHILDRE.
IT'S COUNTER INDUE TIVE THAT'S
SUPPOSED TO BE THE OTHER WAY.
>> WHAT HAPPENS IS THEY FEEL
LIKE IT SHOULD HAVE BEEN THEM.
THERE'S NOTHING WORSE FOR A
PARENT TO GO THROUGH.
AND AT THIS POINT WHEN YOU ARE
SEEING THESE PARENTS ARE IN
SHOCK, THEY ARE NUMB, THEY ARE
OVERWHELMED WITH THEIR FEELINGS.
THEY MAY NOT EVEN FEEL THEIR
FEELINGS.
THEY HAVE BEEN ALMOST
DISASSOCIATED WITH THEIR
FEELINGS.
YOU TALK TO PEOPLE AT THIS STAGE
AND THEY WILL TELL YOU LIKE THEY
ARE GOING THROUGH THE MOTIONS
AND THEY ARE LIKE A ROBOT.
ACTUALLY SOMETIMES IT'S THE
PEOPLE AROUND THEM THAT ARE
LITERALLY KIND OF CARRYING
THROUGH THESE VERY DIFFICULT
STEPS.
>> HOW DO THEY COME OUT OF IT?
WHEN DO YOU GET OUT FROM UNDER
THE CLOUD?
YOU HAVE OTHER CHILDREN AT HOME.
CHILDREN WHO ARE SUFFERING AS
WELL.
>> SOMETIMES THAT'S WHAT BRINGS
YOU AT LEAST INTO LIVING.
IT DOESN'T NECESSARILY BRING YOU
INTO A FULL HAPPY LIFE BECAUSE
THERE'S A WHOLE THAT REALLY
DOESN'T GET FILLED BUT WHAT THEY
DO IS FIND A WAY EVENTUALLY IF
THEY CAN TO HAVE THEIR GRIEF
TRACK IN THEIR LIFE AND THEN THE
LIVING TRACK OF THEIR LIFE.
AND THEY SOMETIME HAVE TO KEEP A
FOOT IN BOTH WORLDS AND
EVENTUALLY THE LIVING PART CAN
GET BIGGER.
>> YOU DO THIS FOR A LIVING.
YOU RECOMMEND THE PARENTS WHO
ARE BURYING THEIR CHILDREN THAT
THEY GET COUNSELING, STAY IN
TOUCH AND NOT BE WITHDRAWN AND
WHAT ELSE?
>> WELL, I THINK WHAT YOU SEE
OVER TIME IS THAT EVERYBODY HAS
A DIFFERENT REACTION.
THERE AREN'T STAGES OF GRIEF.
IT IS THROUGH OUT YOUR LIFE.
IT INVOLVES STAGES.
AT A CERTAIN TIME YOUR FRIENDS
CHILDREN ARE GRADUATING FROM
HIGH SCHOOL AND YOURS AREN'T.
YOU START TO PAY ATTENTION TO
HOW YOU ARE DOING.
THERE ARE A CERTAIN NUMBER WHO
NEED SPECIFIC HELP TO HELP THEM
LEARN HOW TO COPE AND ACTUALLY
CAN BE VERY SUCCESSFUL WITH AND
FIND SOME KIND OF MEANING AND
NEW PEOPLE IN THEIR LIFE.
>> THEY TALK ABOUT POST
TRAUMATIC STRESS SYNDROME IN
WARS.
THESE KIDS HAVE SEEN HELL A LOT
OF THEM.
>> THEY WERE IN A MINI WAR WHEN
YOU THINK ABOUT IT.
THE RAMPAGE.
WHEN I FIRST HEARD THE NEWS I
WAS LIKE IS THIS ANOTHER
TERRORIST ATTACK.
IT ALMOST SOUNDED LIKE THAT.
WHAT POST TRAUMATIC STRESS
DISORDER IS HAVING OO FRIGHTENE.
WE USUALLY WALK AROUND THINKING
WE ARE SAFE AND THE WORLD IS
SAFE.
THERE IS A RECOGNITION THE WORLD
IS NO LONGER SAFE OR IN YOUR
CONTROL.
>> WE HEARD LAST NIGHT ABOUT A
CHILD WHO WAS AFRAID TO HAVE HER
FATHER LEAVE HER SIDE FOR GOOD
REASONS.
>> THERE WILL BE REGRESSION,
NIGHTMARES SOMETIMES PANIC
ATTACKS.
FEAR TO GO NEAR THE SCHOOL, TO
BE SEPARATED FROM A PARENT.
MAYBE TO HAVE SLEEP OVERS.
SO PARENTS CAN JUST BE AWARE OF
THIS WORK WITH THEIR
PEDIATRICIAN.
SOUNDS LIKE THE TOWN IS REALLY
HELPING OUT AND BEING A RESOURCE
FOR THE ENTIRE COMMUNITY.
>> THE QUESTION THAT -- THE
BIGGER QUESTION IS HOW DOES THE
TOWN HEEL?
>> IT WAS PUT TOGETHER.
DON'T YOU THINK THEY HAVE EACH
OTHER?
BEING CONNECTED TO EACH OTHER.
ALSO NOT TOMORROW NOT JUST NEXT
WEEK BUT IT IS OVER MANY MONTHS
SO YOU KEEP REACHING OUT SO
THESE PEOPLE DON'T FEEL ALONE.
>> THERE WAS NO QUESTION THAT
EVERYONE IN THAT TOWN WAS
AFFECTED IN ONE WAY OR ANOTHER.
HOW HARD IS IT TO IDENTIFY ONE
WHO MIGHT COMMIT A CRIME LIKE
THIS?
>> I DON'T KNOW ABOUT THAT BUT
THESE INDIVIDUALS ARE LIKE
LITTLE TERRORISTS OR BIG
TERRORISTS.
THEY LIVE IN THEIR FAMILIES AND
THEIR PARENTS AND OTHERS SPOUSES
AND ADULTS THEY ARE AFRAID OF
THEM.
IT IS DIFFICULT TO GET PEOPLE
LIKE THIS TO STAY IN HELL TO
DETAIN THEM.
LET ME TELL YOU THERE IS NO PILL
THAT IS GOING TO CURE THIS
POSITION.
THERE MIGHT BE A PRAYER BUT
PEOPLE WHO ARE EVIL ARE NOT
AMENABLE TO MENTAL HEALTH
PROFESSIONALS.
>>> THE ILLNESS CONVERSATION ON
AMERICA WHICH I THOUGHT WAS
EXCELLENT.
THERE IS TALK YOU CAN'T GET HELP
UNLESS THEY START COMMITTING
CRIMES.
>> THIS IS AFTER THEY COMMITTED
A CRIME.
YOU ARE ABSOLUTELY CORRECT
GETTING THEM HELP BEFORE THAT IS
LIKE CLIMBING MOUNT EVEREST
BAREFOOT.
>> WE NEED TO TALK ABOUT THE
DEEPER ISSUES SO WE DON'T HAVE
THIS HAPPEN A YEAR FROM NOW.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT THE CAUSE FOR
THESE SPREE KILLINGS REALLY IS.
>> ALL OF THE BURIALS AS A
COUNTRY HOW DO WE DEAL WITH
THAT.
MY HEART BREAKS.
I HA
I AM A MOTHER.
I HAVE SEEN CHILD ABUSE AND
HOMICIDE CASES.
THIS ONE JUST BREAKS YOUR HEART.
>> I THINK WHAT YOU DO IS YOU
PAY ATTENTION TO THE PEOPLE THAT
ARE RIGHT IN YOUR WORLD TO HELP
THEM WITH THIS AND ALSO LEARN TO
BE HE KNOWS IS TIVE TO THE OTHER
PEOPLE WHO ALSO NEED EXTRA HELP.
>> GREAT PANEL DR. LESLIE,
DR. GOOD MAN AND DR. STABENOW.
>>> THESE ARE WITHOUT A DOUBT
THE MOST DIFFICULT OF TIMES.
CAN FAITH HEAL ALL WOUNDS?
[ sniffs ] I HAVE A COLD.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
7,000 STUDENTS DROP OUT
EVERY SCHOOL DAY.
THAT'S A LINE OF DESKS
MORE THAN 4 MILES LONG.
KEEP STUDENTS IN SCHOOL.
VISIT BOOSTUP.ORG
AND TAKE THE FIRST STEP.
>> LET THE LITTLE CHILDREN COME
TO ME JESUS SAID.
DO NOT HINDER THEM.
FOR TO SUCH BELONGS THE KINGDOM
OF HEAVEN.
GOD HAS CALLED THEM ALL HOME.
MAY GOD BLESS AND KEEP THOSE WE
HAVE LOST IN HIS HEAVENLY PLACE.
MAY HE GRACE THOSE WE STILL HAVE
WITH HIS HOLY COMFORT.
>> WITH ME IS JACK MONDAY A
MEMBER OF BILLY GRAHAM'S RAP HID
RESPONSE TEAM AND JARROD MURRAY
PAST FORE
PASTOR OF HOLY FAMILY PARISH.
>> I AM GOING TO START WITH YOU.
YOU WERE PART OF BILLY GRAHAM'S
RAPID RESPONSE TEAM.
I UNDERSTAND YOUR TEAM ARRIVED
IN NEWTOWN ON FRIDAY THE VERY
G
DAY THIS HAPPENED.
TELL US WHAT YOU SAW?
>> YES, AFTER ARRIVING WE MADE
CONTACT WITH THE STATE POLICE
AND THE FIRE HERE IN NEWTOWN.
BECAUSE OF OUR CHAPLAIN HAVING A
POLICE BACK GROUND AND FIRE
BACKGROUND THEY WERE WELCOMELED
IMMEDIATELY AT THE VOLUNTEER
FIRE DEPARTMENTS AND ESCORTED TO
THE EMERGENCY OPERATIONS CENTER.
>> AND JACK YOU DO THIS
REGULARLY AS PARTED OF THIS
RESPONSE TEAM YOU GO ALL OVER
THE COUNTRY.
>> ACTUALLY, WE HAVE BEEN DOING
THIS SINCE SEPTEMBER 11TH WE
HAVE RESPONDED TO 154 DISASTERS
TEN OF WHICH HAVE BEEN ON MASS
SHOOTINGS.
>> I AM GOING TOING TO YOU
FATHER MURRAY.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR BEING WITH
US TODAY.
I GUESS THE QUESTION WE ALL ASK
IS AN ALL KNOWING POWERFUL
LOVING GOD ALLOW THIS TO HAPPEN.
>> THE WAY I LOOK AT THE
QUESTION IS, IF YOU WANT TO KNOW
WHAT THE WORLD IS LIKE WITHOUT
GOD THIS IS AN EXAMPLE.
THIS MAN TURNED AWAY FROM GOD
OBVIOUSLY AND DID SOMETHING
TREMENDOUS.
KILLING YOUR OWN MOTHER AND
KILLING INNOCENT CHILDREN SO
AGAINST NATURE COMPLETELY
AGAINST THE TEN COMMANDMENTS.
GOD IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR THIS.
WE ARE AS HUMAN BEINGS ARE FREE
CHOICES.
I NOTICE THAT PUBLIC REACTION IS
NOT TO TURN AWAY FROM GOD AND
BLAME HIM.
IT'S TO GO TO GOD AND PRAY FOR
SYMPATHY AND THE VICTIMS AND
CONSTELLATION.
>> YOU KNOW FATHER CAN YOU
UNDERSTAND A PARENT WHO LOST AN
ANGEL AND WILL BE BURYING THESE
CHILDREN THIS WEEK CAN TURN AWAY
AND SAY, HOW COULD GOD TAKE MY
CHILD FROM ME?
>>> OO GOD DIDN'T DO IT.
THE MESSAGE WE SAY IS GOD LOVES
THAT CHILD.
THAT'S THE HOPE OF CHRISTIANITY.
JESUS HAVING HIS LITTLE ONES.
THE ANSWER IS MORE COMPLICATED
THAN SOMEBODY MIGHT LIKE.
WE NEVER KNOW WHEN THE CALL IS
GOING TO COME.
THIS IS HORRIBLE IT SHOULDN'T
HAPPEN.
ON THE OTHER HAND IT'S A PROOF
WE HAVE TO FIGHT EVIL NOT
TOLERATE IT.
>> I WENT TO CATHOLIC SCHOOLS
AND I AM A CATHOLIC.
I STAUND WE HAVE BEEN GIVEN FREE
WILL, BUT YOU KNOW THE ABILITY
TO CHOOSE WHAT WE WANT TO DO IS
STILL -- IT ALLOWS THOSE OTHER
PEOPLE TO CHOOSE EVIL.
IT IS SOMETHING WE CAN'T STOP.
>> WE CAN OFFER ANOTHER LAW, A
LAW OF LOVE AND TRAINING IN
SYMPATHY.
IT WILL BE INTERESTING TO READ
WHAT PART RELIGION PLAYED IN HIS
PLAN'S LIFE, IF ANYTHING.
>> WE NEED TO BE MORE RAE LIG
GUS AS A NATION.
>> JACK MONDAY, WE HEAR FROM THE
FATHER ROBY PARKER OF ONE OF THE
CHILDREN.
HE SAID, I AM NOT ANGRY.
I FOR GIVE.
DOES THAT SURPRISE YOU?
HAVE YOU HEARD THAT BEFORE?
>> I HAVE.
AS WE RESPOND TO DISASTERS.
WE MEET WITH PEOPLE WHO HAVE A
FOUNDATION OF FAITH.
A FAITH IN CHRIST.
WE HAVE PEOPLE WHO DON'T HAVE A
FOUNDATION OF FAITH AT ALL.
IT IS A TESTIMONY OF WHAT GODS
HAS DONE IN SOMEONE'S LIFE THAT
IS FOUNDATIONAL.
THEY HAVE A FAITH IN CHRIST.
THEY KNOW THAT IS THEIR SOURCE
OF HOPE, THEIR SOURCE OF COMFORT
AND WHEN THEY DO TURN TO CHRIST
AND TO GOD'S WORD THAT OFFERS
THAT HOPE THEY ARE THE ONES.
NOT TO SAY THEY DON'T HURT, THEY
DON'T SUFFER, IT'S STILL AN
AGONIZING LOSS FOR THEM.
NO DIFFERENT THAN ANY ONE ELSE.
IT LOOKS LIKE A REALITY WHEN YOU
HAVE A FAITH IN CHRIST AND YOU
CAN PUT YOUR COMPETENCE IN HIM
AND FOCUS HIS FOLKS ON HIS TEAM.
OO WILL OO IT IS NOT END OF THE
STORY.
THERE IS HOPE.
>> FATHER MURRAY FOR THOSE
PEOPLE WHO HAVEN'T HAD GOD IN
THEIR LIVES, WHO HAVEN'T BEEN
PRACTICING RELIGION PEOPLE SAY I
DON'T BELIEVE IN GOD.
DO YOU THINK THERE'S A CHANCE
THEY WILL COME TO GOD AS A
RESULT OF THIS?
>> THE ERUPTION OF HELL INTO AN
OTHERWISE PEACEFUL COMMUNITY
THERE IS MORE TO LIFE THAN WHAT
WE SIMPLY CHOOSE TO DO.
THE TO TURN TO GOD AND KNOW
WHAT'S RIGHT.
>> I WANT TO THANK YOU FOR BEING
WITH US AND THANK YOU FOR ALL
THAT YOU DO.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US THIS
EVENING.
>> THAT'S IT FOR OUR SPECIAL
EDITION OF "JUSTICE."
AS WE SIGN OFF TONIGHT OUR
THOUGHTS AND PRAYERS GO TO ALL
OF THOSE AFFECTED BY THE HORROR
THAT HAS VISITED US THIS FAPAST
FRIDAY.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WULGS.
Um...
Uh...
Hm...
Umm...
Uh...
Oh !
The Windows Phone 8X
by HTC on Verizon.
It features easy
to navigate live tiles
that are simple
to customize.
Just pin what matters most
right to your homescreen.
Exclusively with Data Sense--
a feature that makes the most
of you plan.
Only on Verizon.
[ Male Announcer ]
JILL AND HER MOUTH HAVE LIVED
A GREAT LIFE.
BUT SHE HAS SOME DENTAL ISSUES
SHE'S NOT HAPPY ABOUT.
SO I INTRODUCED JILL
TO CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SELECTED FOR PEOPLE OVER 50.
PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE IS A
TOOTHPASTE THAT DEFENDS AGAINST
TENDER, INFLAMED GUMS,
SENSITIVITY AND WEAK ENAMEL.
CONDITIONS PEOPLE OVER 50
EXPERIENCE.
CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SO JILL CAN KEEP LIVING
THE GOOD LIFE.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
SO JILL CAN KEEP LIVING
THE GOOD LIFE.
UNTIL I HAD THE SHINGLES.
I HAVE NEVER ENCOUNTERED
SUCH A BURNING SENSATION...
IT WAS LIKE A RED RASH.
LIKE SOMEBODY HAD SET A BAG
OF HOT CHARCOAL ON MY NECK.
I HAD NO IDEA IT
CAME FROM CHICKENPOX.
IT'S SOMETHING YOU
NEVER WANT TO ENCOUNTER.