>> IT IS A TOWN WITH FIVE
STOPLIGHTS.
FOUR STOPLIGHTS.
>> WOW, OKAY, COOL.
>> SHERROD, WHAT IS UP WITH
YOU AND KATIE COURIC AND JOY
BEHAR.
>> TOMORROW NIGHT I WILL BE ON
CURRENT TV AND DO COMICS WITH
BENEFITS WITH JOY BEHAR AND
COLIN QUINN AND IT IS TOMORROW
AT 9:00 ON CURRENT.
NEXT WEDNESDAY I WILL BE ON
THE YEAR WITH KATIE COURIC.
IT IS ON AT 9:30 ON ABC.
WE TALK ABOUT EVERYTHING THAT
HAPPENED IN 2012.
>> COOL.
>> I HAVE TO WORK.
I HAVE TO EAT.
>> I JUST WANT TO BE ON THE
BUS WITH GREG.
>> YOU WILL BE ON THE BUS WITH
ME.
>> I MUST WAIVE.
TONIGHT.
>> THE ONLY THING LEFT FOR
BARACK OBAMA TO DO IS TO WORK
ON THIRD WORLD DICTATOR AND
PUT ALL THESE GUYS IN JAIL.
>> Bill: HARRY BELL FONTY IS
TALKING ABOUT ME YOUR HUMBLE
CORRESPONDENT AND OTHERS
SECULAR PROGRESSIVE AGENDA.
CONTINUING THE FAR LEFT ON THE
MARCH
♪ YOU BELONG WITH ME
♪ GIRLS WERE UNDENIABLE
♪ WE GOT IT ON TOP.
>> Bill: YOUNG SINGERS TAYLOR
SMITH AND PERRY.
>> DEFINE THE FISCAL CLIFF FOR
ME.
>> SOME IMAGINARY CLIFF
SOMEWHERE IN MY MIND THAT WE
ARE ALL GOING TO JUMP OOFF OF.
>> Bill: JESSE WATTERS QUIZES
THE FOLKS ABOUT THE INTENSE
BUDGET DEBATE.
>> WE'RE GOING TO GO OFF THE
CLIFF ON JANUARY 2ND.
>> OH YOU MEAN THE END OF THE
WORLD TYPE OF THING?
>> Bill: CAUTION, YOU WHERE TO
ENTER THE NO SPIN ZONE.
THE FACTOR BEGINS RIGHT NOW.
>> Bill: HI, I'M BILL
O'REILLY.
THANKS FOR WATCHING US
TONIGHT.
SECULAR FORCES ON THE MARCH,
THAT IS THE SUBJECT OF THIS
EVENING'S TALKING POINTS MEMO.
AS WE HAVE BEEN REPORTING,
SOME COMMITTED LEFT WING
AMERICANS HAVE BEEN EMBOLDENED
BY THE RE-ELECTION OF
PRESIDENT OBAMA.
YOU ARE SEEING THAT NOW IN THE
BUDGET NEGOTIATIONS AS THE
PRESIDENT AND HIS SIDE ARE NOT
IN ANY COMPROMISING MOOD.
I SAW IT FIRSTHAND THIS WEEK
WHEN I WAS DOWN IN WASHINGTON.
THERE IS ARROGANCE AND
CONDESCENSION IN MANY LEFT
WING PRECINCTS DESPITE THE
FACT THAT U.N. AMBASSADOR
TODAY SUSAN RICE IS OUT OF
CONSIDERATION FOR SECRETARY OF
STATE.
WE WILL MORE ON THAT WITH BOB
BECKEL COMING UP.
THE MORE SECULAR PROGRESSIVES
UNDERSTAND NOW IS THEIR TIME
IN HISTORY.
THE AGENDA IS CLEAR.
ABOVE ALL THE SECULAR FORCES
WANT TO CHANGE THE ECONOMY.
THEY WANT THE GOVERNMENT TO
RUN IT AND PROVIDE GRADDLE TO
GRAVE ENTITLEMENTS FOR THOSE
AMERICANS WHO CANNOT OR WILL
NOT PROVIDE FOR THEMSELVES.
THE LEFT ALSO WANTS TO CONTROL
PROFITS IN THE PRIVATE SECTOR
TAKING AS MUCH MONEY AS
POSSIBLE AWAY FROM THE
ACHIEVERS AND THE
CORPORATIONS.
AGAIN, WITH THE INTENT TO
REDISTRICT THE CASH.
SO THAT'S AGENDA NUMBER ONE.
NUMBER TWO, IS TO OBLITERATE
SOME AMERICAN TRADITIONS.
GAY MARRIAGE, NOT ABOUT
MATRIMONY ANYMORE.
IT'S ABOUT CIVIL RIGHTS.
AND IF YOU OPPOSE GAY MARRIAGE
YOU ARE A HATER, A RIGHTS
DENIER.
LEGALIZED NARCOTICS, THE LEFT
SEES DRUG USERS AS VICTIMS AND
BELIEVES NO ONE HAS A RIGHT TO
STAND BETWEEN AN AMERICAN AND
INTOXICATION MUCH.
ON THAT NOTE THE "NEW YORK
TIMES" RAN A FRONT PAGE
ARTICLE YESTERDAY LAMENTING
TOUGH MANDATORY PRISON
SENTENCES FOR DRUG DEALERS.
THE LEFT BELIEVES THEY ARE NOT
VIOLENT OFFENDERS.
SO IF YOU ARE SELLING METH,
HEROIN, COCAINE, THAT'S NOT AN
ACT THAT CAUSES HARM OR PAIN
TO ANOTHER PERSON, OH, NO.
ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
THOSE OF YOU WHO KNOW
FIRSTHAND ABOUT ADDICTION KNOW
HOW CRAZY THAT POINT OF VIEW
IS.
PEOPLE WHO SELL DRUGS ARE THE
LOWEST RUNG.
THEY ARE COMMITTING VIOLENCE
AGAINST OTHER HUMAN BEINGS.
PERIOD.
"TIMES" ARTICLE SAYS A HALF
MILLION PEOPLE ARE IN PRISON
FOR DRUG OFFENSES IN THE
U.S.A.
10 TIMES THE NUMBER THAN IN
1980.
THAT SOUNDS BAD, DOESN'T IT?
WHAT THE PAPER DOES NOT, DOES
NOT TELL YOU IS THAT VIOLENT
RHYME IN -- CRIME IN AMERICA
HAS BEEN CUT IN HALF SINCE THE
TOUGH MANDATORY PRISON
SENTENCES WERE INSTITUTED.
THE COUNTRY IS MUCH SAFER
BECAUSE HARD CORE CRIMINALS
ARE DOING HARD TIME.
THAT'S A FACT.
NO ONE SHOULD FEEL SORRY FOR
KILLERS, RAPISTS AND DRUG
PUSHERS.
NOW, BECAUSE I DO COMMENTARY
LIKE THIS, LAYING OUT THE
PROGRESSIVE AGENDA, I'M A BIG
THREAT TO THEM.
LISTEN TO THIS INCREDIBLE
SOUND BITE FROM COMMITTED LEFT
WING GUY HARRY BELL BELAFONTE
HE SAYS PEOPLE LIKE ME WHO
OPPOSE PRESIDENT OBAMA AND
LIBERAL AGENDA ON SOME THINGS
SHOULD BE DEALT WITH.
>> WHAT FASCINATES ME IS THAT
IN THE PHASE OF MILLIONS OF
AMERICANS EXPRESSING THEIR
DESIRE THE WHOLE POLITICAL
ESTABLISHMENT DEFINING ITS
GAME THAT THERE SHOULD BE THIS
LINGERING INFESTATION OF
REALLY CORRUPT PEOPLE WHO SIT
TRYING TO DISMANTLE THE WISHES
OF THE PEOPLE, THE MANDATE
THAT HAS BEEN GIVEN TO BARACK
OBAMA AND I DON'T KNOW WHAT
MORE THEY WANT.
THE ONLY THING LEFT FOR BARACK
OBAMA TO DO IS TO ORGANIZE A
THIRD WORLD DICTATOR AND PUT
ALL THESE GUYS IN JAIL.
VIOLATING THE AMERICAN DESIRE.
>> Bill: I GUESS VIOLATING THE
AMERICAN DESIRE IS A FELONY
NOW, RIGHT, HARRY?
MAYBE THE GUY WAS JUST
KIDDING.
MAYBE.
BUT, BELIEVE ME, ANYONE IN
THIS COUNTRY WHO CHALLENGES
THE SECULAR PROGRESSIVE AGENDA
IS GOING TO GET HAMMERED.
THESE PEOPLE ARE ON A MISSION.
THEY WANT A COMPLETELY
DIFFERENT AMERICA.
A COUNTRY THAT EMBRACES SOCIAL
JUSTICE, LIBERTINE BEHAVIOR
AND SECULAR IN EVERY WAY.
THAT BRINGS US TO THE
CHRISTMAS CONTROVERSY WHICH IS
SYMBOLIC, SYMBOLIC OF THE
ENTIRE CULTURE WAR.
WAR ON CHRISTMAS IS OVER AND
TRADITIONAL FORCES HAVE WON.
THE MAGAZINE CITING RETAIL
STORES ALLOWING EMPLOYEES TO
NOW SAY MERRY CHRISTMAS TO THE
SHOPPERS.
A FEW YEARS AGO SOME
CORPORATIONS WERE FORBIDDEN.
THEY WERE TELLING EMPLOYEES
THEY COULDN'T DO THAT.
WELL WAR ON CHRISTMAS HAS
LARGELY GONE OUR WAY.
DON'T THINK THE DEAL IS OVER.
IT'S NOT.
LISTEN TO NEXT CHANGE ABOUT
THE CHRISTMAS HOLIDAY ON "THE
TODAY SHOW" EARLIER THIS WEEK.
>> I FOCUS ON, HONESTLY THE
RELIGION PART OF IT.
I REALLY AND TRULY DO.
SO I CAN'T OUTSOURCE THAT PART
OF IT.
CAN I SEND YOU TO GET MY TREE
BUT I CAN'T HELP -- YOU CAN'T
HELP ME.
>> I DON'T LIKE THE RELIGION
PART.
I THINK RELIGION IS WHAT MUCKS
THE WHOLE THING UP.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Bill: SOME AMERICANS AGREE
WITH DR. SNYDERMAN THERE THAT
BECAUSE CHRISTMAS HONORS JESUS
WHOM SOME PEOPLE BELIEVE IS
GOD, IT IS MUCKED UP.
MUCKED UP SO TO SPEAK.
TV WRITER FRAZIER MOORE
SECULAR ZEALOT MASSACRE RATING
AS A ZEALOT FOR THE ASSOCIATED
PRESS TURNING HOLIDAY WAR ZONE
O'REILLY IS ALL FOR KEEPING
CHRIST IN CHRISTMAS.
AT THE SAME TIME HE PROCLAIMS
THAT EVERYONE, NO MATTER THEIR
FAITH, SHOULD CALL A CHRISTMAS
TREE A CHRISTMAS TREE AND
KNOCK OFF THEIR WHINING.
NO ONE INTELLIGENT PERSON
COULD POSSIBLY SEE A SECULAR
POSSIBLY SEE A SECULAR DISPLAY
OF INTERIOR MINISTRY POSITION
OF PHILOSOPHY.
NEVER MIND THAT WEBSTER'S NEW
WORLD COLLEGE DICTIONARY
DEFINES CHRISTIANITY
CHRISTIANS COLLECTIVELY THE
CHRISTIAN RELIGION, UNQUOTE.
MR. MOORE IS OFFEND OD THAT I
WANT A CHRISTMAS TREE TO BE
CALLED A CHRISTMAS TREE.
HE SEES IT AS AN ATTACK ON HIS
VALUE SYSTEM.
MOORE IS ONE OF THE LEGIONS OF
MEDIA WHO HAVE FORMED A
SECULAR CLOWN POSEY.
A BUNCH OF PEOPLE WHO HAVE NO
BLANKING IDEA WHAT THIS
COUNTRY WAS FOUNDED ON.
SO I'M GOING TO SPEAK VERY
SLOWLY TO YOU FRAZIER, PLEASE
TAKE SOME NOTES AND HAVE THAT
DICTIONARY HANDY.
CHRISTIANITY IS A RELIGION FOR
THOSE WHO BELIEVE JESUS IS IS
GOD.
AND FOR THOSE WHO JOIN A
SPECIFIC CHURCH TO CELEBRATE
THAT BELIEF.
BUT CHRISTIANITY IS A
PHILOSOPHY TO PEOPLE LIKE
THOMAS JEFFERSON WHO DID NOT
BELIEVE THAT JESUS WAS THE
DEITY.
AND MR. JEFFERSON, AS WELL AS
MANY OF THE FOUNDING FATHERS,
INCORPORATED THE
JUDEO-CHRISTIAN PHILOSOPHY
INTO THE CONSTITUTION.
THAT'S WHY THE 10 COMMANDMENTS
HANG IN THE SUPREME COURT
BUILDING.
ARE YOU WITH ME SO FAR,
FRAZIER?
IMAGES OF THE MANGER SCENE IN
THE PUBLIC SQUARE SIMPLY HONOR
THE BABY JESUS, THE HUMAN
BEING.
THE BABY IS NOT SITTING AT THE
RIGHT HAND OF GOD.
HE IS LAYING THERE FLANKED BY
HIS PARENTS.
IT'S LIKE THE MARTIN LUTHER
KING JR. HOLIDAY, FRAZIER.
DR. KING HONORED AS A MAN WHO
HELPED HUMANITY.
AT CHRISTMAS, JESUS IS HONORED
AS A MAN WHO HELPED HUMANITY.
IF YOU WANT TO BELIEVE JESUS
IS GOD, THEN YOU CAN TAKE THAT
FURTHER AS IS YOUR
CONSTITUTIONAL RIGHT.
IF YOU DON'T BUY THE RELIGIOUS
ASPECT.
CAN YOU JUST CELEBRATE THE
FEDERAL HOLIDAY THAT WAS
SIGNED INTO LAW PRESIDENT
GRANT, WITH NO PROVISION,
FRAZIER, THAT EVERYONE WORSHIP
JESUS.
NOT PART OF THE DEAL.
ARE YOU STILL WITH ME?
OR IS THIS TOO COMPLICATED FOR
YOU?
HERE IS THE BIG PICTURE.
THE SECULAR PROGRESSIVE AGENDA
IS OPPOSED BY MANY PEOPLE OF
FAITH.
ABORTION, GAY MARRIAGE,
LEGALIZED DRUGS, ALL OF THOSE
THINGS ARE OPPOSED BY MANY
RELIGIOUS AMERICANS.
THAT IS WHY SOME FAR LEFT
FOLKS WANT TO DIMINISH
JUDEO-CHRISTIAN TRADITION AND
RENAME THE CHRISTMAS TREE THE
HOLIDAY TREE.
THE LESS CHRISTMAS, THE
BETTER.
THE SECULAR PEOPLE ARE NOW
MORE POWERFUL THAN EVER.
THEIR GUY HAS BEEN RIO HE
ELECTED AND OPPOSING FORCES
ARE SCATTERED.
AND THAT IS WHAT IS GOING ON
IN AMERICA ON DECEMBER 13TH,
2012.
AND THAT'S THE MEMO.
NEXT ON THE RUNDOWN, WE HAVE
REACTION FROM BOB BECKEL,
LAURA INGRAHAM ON THE RAGING
CULTURE WAR IN AMERICA.
LATER MEGYN KELLY ON A U.S.
MARINE INCARCERATED MEXICO FOR
ABSOLUTELY NO REASON AT ALL.
THIS IS OUTRAGEOUS, WE'RE
TRYINGNGNGNG
>> Bill: CONTINUING NOW WITH
LEAD STORY SECULAR FRSES ON
THE MARCH.
HERE NOW CO-HOST OF THE FIVE
BOB BECKEL.
WHERE AM I GOING WRONG.
>> TELL ME TO BE PITHY.
>> Bill: RIGHT.
>> EVERYWHERE.
>> Bill: NOT RIGHT ON ANYTHING
EVEN FRAZIER MOORE A PINHEAD.
>> I DON'T KNOW WHO FRAZIER
MOORE WAS.
HE JUST GOT HIS BUTT SKINNED
BY YOU IF I WERE HIM I
PROBABLY WOULDN'T BE SAYING
THINGS BUT.
>> Bill: HE SHOULD WRITE WHAT
HE BELIEVES IS TRUE BUT IF HE
DOESN'T KNOW THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN CHRISTIAN PHILOSOPHY
AND THE CHRISTIAN RELIGION AND
MOST PEOPLE DON'T.
NOT MOST PEOPLE BUT A LOT OF
PEOPLE DON'T.
>> THEY DON'T, EARTH THAT.
THE WAR ON CHRISTMAS.
YOU FOUGHT THE GREAT BATTLE,
YOU WON THE BATTLE, LET'S MOVE
ON.
IS THERE SOMETHING ELSE YOU
WANT TO TALK ABOUT.
>> Bill: I'M NOT GOING TO MOVE
ON.
IT'S SYMBOLIC OF THE CULTURE
WAR.
>> WHAT CULTURE WAR.
>> Bill: YOU DON'T BELIEVE
CULTURE WAR.
YOU DON'T BELIEVE SECULAR.
>> TRADITIONAL AND SECULAR
AMERICANS?
SO SECULAR AMERICANS ARE NOT
TRADITIONAL AMERICANS?
IS THAT WHAT YOU ARE
SUGGESTING.
>> Bill: NO THEY WANT CHANGE.
SECULAR PROGRESSIVES WANT TO
CHANGE THE COUNTRY.
>> IT'S MIND BOGGLING TO ME.
>> Bill: IT'S MIND BOGGLING.
>> YEAH YOUR RADIO COMMENTARY
FOR EXAMPLE WAS BEYOND BELIEF.
GAY MARRIAGES.
DO YOU KNOW THAT A MAJORITY OF
AMERICANS FAVOR GAY MARRIAGE.
>> Bill: I DON'T OPPOSE GAY
MARRIAGE I'M NOT SAYING THAT
I'M SAYING IT'S A ISSUE
DEFINED AS CIVIL RIGHTS.
>> YOU SAY A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE
AGAINST GAY MARRIAGE.
>> NOT MAJORITY.
>> HALF THE COUNTRY.
>> PEOPLE WHO OPPOSE IT ARE
MOSTLY BLACK
AFRICAN-AMERICANS.
>> Bill: YOU ARE MEANDERING
HERE NOW.
>> I'M NOT ME AN GEAR DERING
ANYWAY.
>> MY THESIS THERE IS A RAGING
CULTURE WAR AND YOUR SIDE
SECULAR PROGRESSIVES HAVE BEEN
EMBOLDENED BY THE RE-ELECTION
OF PRESIDENT OBAMA.
WE HEARD FROM HARRY BELAFONTE
CALLING FOR INCARCERATION.
>> I WILL TELL YOU ONE THING
THAT WOULD BE A START.
>> YOU WOULD LOVE THAT?
YOU WOULD RUN WILD WITH THAT.
>> HARRY BELAFONTE WAS JOKING.
>> Bill: HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT?
I DIDN'T SEE HIM SMILING, DID
YOU?
>> IF YOU TOOK THAT SERIOUSLY.
>> Bill: HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT
HE WAS JOKING?
HOW?
>> HE LAUGHED.
>> Bill: HE DIDN'T LAUGH.
>> THE OTHER GUY INTERVIEWED
HIM LAUGH.
>> Bill: THE OTHER GUY LAUGHED
BECAUSE IT WAS SO INSANE.
>> YOU THINK HARRY BELAFONTE
WANTS TO LOCK YOU UP?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
I THINK IT'S A WORTHWHILE
EXERCISE.
>> Bill: I THINK HARRY
BELAFONTE WOULD PROBABLY
EMBRACE ANYTHING THAT WOULD
GIVE HIM WHAT HE WANTS
POLITICALLY.
>> CAN WE GO BACK TO WHAT
PEOPLE WANT POLITICALLY?
YOU KEEP SAYING THE SECULAR
LEFT AS IF THE SECULAR LEFT
REPRESENTS MAYBE 2 O% OF THE
DEMOGRAPHICS OF THIS COUNTRY.
VIRTUALLY THINGS YOU HAVE COME
UP HERE, FOR EXAMPLE, TAX
INCREASES FOR THE WEALTHY
PEOPLE THAT'S ACROSS THE
BOARD.
REPUBLICANS WANT IT, TOO.
A THE LOVE REPUBLICANS.
INDEPENDENTS BY BIG NUMBERS.
DEMOCRATS BY BIG NUMBERS.
>> Bill: IT'S NOT ABOUT A
LITTLE TAX HIKE.
IT'S ABOUT THE GOVERNMENT
TAKING OVER THE ECONOMY.
THAT'S WHAT SECULAR
PROGRESSIVES WANT.
THEY WANT TO DOLL OUT SOCIAL
JUSTICE YOU KNOW THAT.
>> I DON'T KNOW THAT.
>> Bill: YOU DON'T KNOW THAT
DO YOU JET OFF TO ALBANIA?
>> YOU ARE THE ONE WHO JETS
OFF.
JO JET OFF.
I DON'T HAVE A JET TO JET OFF.
>> Bill: DON'T EVEN
ACKNOWLEDGE THERE IS A CULTURE
WAR IN THE COUNTRY.
>> PAT BUCHANAN HAD THE
CULTURE WAR THAT WAS 20 YEARS
AGO.
>> Bill: I'M NOT GOING TO GET
THROUGH.
LET'S GO TO SUSAN RICE.
WERE YOU SURPRISED THAT U.N.
AMBASSADOR IS NOW NOT GOING TO
BE IN CONTENTION FOR SECRETARY
OF STATE?
>> NO.
>> Bill: WHY WEREN'T YOU
SURPRISED?
BIG PATEL IN THE SENATE WHEN
THEY HAVE A LOT OF OTHER
THINGS GOING UP UP THERE.
JOHN KERRY IS A GOOD FALL BACK
AND THAT'S WHERE THEY ARE
GOING TO GO.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA IS MAD.
HE WOULD HAVE LIKED TO HAVE
HAD SUSAN RICE.
>> I THINK HE WOULD HAVE.
>> HE WAS ASHAMED THAT SHE WAS
UNFAIRLY TREATED.
DO YOU BELIEVE SHE WAS
>> SURE.
>> Bill: SHE WAS.
>> HOW WAS SHE UNFAIRLY
TREATED?
>> PEOPLE MADE ACQUISITIONS
ABOUT WHAT SHE SAID IN THOSE
TALK SHOWS AND SPEAKING
DIRECTLY OFF THE INTELLIGENCE
REPORT SHE WAS GIVEN.
>> Bill: WHY DIDN'T SHE
CORRECT THE RECORD LIKE MAYBE
A WEEK LATER THEN.
>> SHE DID CORRECT THE RECORD.
>> Bill: WHEN?
>> WITHIN 8 DAYS AFTERWARDS.
>> Bill: WHERE?
>> FIRST OF ALL I THINK IT WAS
IN THE U.N.
>> YOU THINK?
>> SHE DIDN'T MAKE A U.N.
STATEMENT.
>> I SAID SHE WAS IN NEW YORK
WHEN SHE MADE THE STATEMENT.
YOU WANT TO FIGHT THIS
BENGHAZI THING ALL OVER AGAIN?
>> Bill: I DON'T WANT TO DO
ANYTHING.
I WANT TO KNOW WHERE SHE
CORRECTED THE RECORD.
>> I THINK IT WAS IN NEW YORK.
>> Bill: IN NEW YORK.
IT WAS AT A CLUB DISCO.
>> I DON'T CARE.
>> Bill: YOU DON'T CARE.
>> I COULD CARE LESS.
THIS IS ONE OF YOUR TYPICAL
LET'S TRAP THIS GUY IN THIS
COMMENT.
I'M NOT GOING TO GET TRAPPED
BY YOU.
>> Bill: CORRECTED THE RECORD
I ASKED YOU WHERE AND YOU SAID
YOU DON'T KNOW.
>> SHE ASKED IF SHE WAS
UNFAIRLY TREATED.
>> Bill: SHE DIDN'T CORRECT
THE RECORD.
>> DO YOU THINK TODAY SHE
WOULD SAY WHAT SHE SAID WAS
ACCURATE.
>> Bill: SHE DIDN'T CORRECT IT
THEN.
SHE KNEW IT WAS WRONG.
>> DO YOU THINK SHE WOULD SAY
THAT?
>> Bill: I DON'T KNOW WHAT SHE
WOULD SAY.
I HOPE SHE COMES ON HERE.
RECAP.
NO CULTURE WAR IN YOUR
OPINION.
>> NONE.
>> Bill: ALL RIGHT.
DR. RICE DID CORRECT THE
RECORD BUT YOU DON'T KNOW
EXACTLY WHERE NEW YORK CITY,
COULD HAVE BEEN THE BRONX,
MAYBE STATEN ISLAND?
>> IT COULD HAVE BEEN IN
BROOKLYN SOMEWHERE WHERE YOU
EAT.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE IT WAS.
>> Bill: YOU ARE RIGHT,
BECKEL.
BOB BECKEL, EVERYBODY, WATCH
HIM ON THE FIVE.
DIRECTLY AHEAD LAURA INGRAHAM
WILL WEIGH IN ON THE SEQ. --
SECULAR PROGRESSIVE AGENDA.
WATTERS WORLD ADDRESSING THE
FOLKS ON THE BUDGET DEBATE
>> IMPACT SEGMENT TONIGHT BY
ALMOST EVERY MEASURE
TRADITIONAL FORCES IN AMERICA
ARE UNDER SIEGE JUST BY WHAT
BOB BECKEL SAYS.
HOW SHOULD INDIVIDUAL
AMERICANS REACT TO THAT ON
BOTH SIDES?
JOINING US NOW FROM WASHINGTON
LAURA INGRAHAM.
ALL RIGHT, YOU HEARD MY
TALKING POINTS AND YOU HEARD
BOB BECKEL AND THE DISCUSSION
GO.
>> FIRST OF ALL DID PURR RENO
PERINO AND GUTFELD PUT
BECKEL'S HEAD IN A DEVICE AND
SQUEEZE IT?
WHAT'S GOING ON.
NO PROBLEMS ON CHRISTMAS.
NO ATTACKS ON RELIGION IN THE
PUBLIC SQUARE.
SUSAN RICE WAS TREATED
UNFAIRLY.
LIVING IN A PARALLEL UNIVERSE
HERE.
LOOK, I THINK MOST PEOPLE
REALIZE THAT AFTER THE
ELECTION AS OFTEN HAPPENS IN
POLITICS THE SIDE THAT WINS,
DEMOCRATS FEEL VERY HEADY,
VERY COCKY.
FEEL LIKE THE COUNTRY HAS
SHIFTED SO MUCH BOTH
POLITICALLY AND CULTURALLY
THAT THEY CAN PUSH THEIR
ISSUES.
>> AND THEY ARE.
>> Laura: PUSH MORE BENEFITS
FOR ILLEGAL IMMIGRANTS.
TAKE THE FIGHT AGAINST
RELIGION AND CHRISTMAS.
AND THEY CAN DO A VARIETY OF
THINGS.
THE PROBLEM WITH THAT IN THE
END, BILL, IS THAT IT'S ALMOST
ALWAYS OVERREACHING ON THE
PART OF THE COCKY PARTY, THE
CONCRETED PARTY.
IN THIS CASE OF COURSE IT'S
THE DEMOCRATS AND MORE LIBERAL
DEMOCRATS.
THEY OVERREACH.
AMERICA KIND OF BRISTLES AND
THE PEOPLE INVARIABLY WILL SAY
WOE WOE WOE WOE WOE, MAYBE WE
DIDN'T LIKE ROMNEY SO MUCH.
MAYBE WE WEREN'T THAT EXCITED
ABOUT HIM BUT WE THARNT
EITHER.
TAKE IT SLOW.
LET US LIVE OUR LIVES AND
DON'T TRY TO PUSH TRADITION
OUT OF ALL ASPECTS OF THE
AMERICAN CULTURE.
I THINK DEMOCRATS ARE AT LISK
OF DOING THAT ONCE AGAIN.
>> Bill: OKAY.
THE PROBLEM IS THAT IF I WERE
A SECULAR PROGRESSIVE.
>> YEAH.
AND I WAS ON THAT SIDE I WOULD
PUT THE PEDAL TO THE METAL THE
PARTY HAS TO ORGANIZE.
OLD LEADERSHIP IS OUT, NEW
LEADERSHIP HAS TO COME BACK
IN.
RATINGS FOR A LOT OF THE
CONSERVATIVE PEOPLE ARE DOWN.
THOSE PEOPLE WHO BACK ROMNEY
BIG TIME AND SAID WIN THE
ELECTION PEOPLE HAVE FLED AND
THEY ARE CONFUSED.
SO IF I'M A SECULAR
PROGRESSIVE AND, LOOK, HARRY
BELAFONTE COMING OUT AND I
DON'T KNOW WHETHER HARRY WAS
KIDDING AROUND OR NOT.
I MEAN, HE WASN'T SMILING BUT
MAYBE HARRY DOESN'T SMILE.
>> IS HE A COMMITTED LEFTIST.
>> Bill: BUT WHEN HE SAYS HEY,
IF YOU DON'T AGREE DESIRE OF
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE, YOU KNOW,
WE HAVE GOT A JAIL CELL FOR
YOU.
YOU KNOW, WE'RE GETTING REALLY
NOW INTO A PRETTY INTERESTING
SITUATION.
>> IT'S LIKE JEFFREY IMMELT
SAYING KIND OF PRAISING CHINA
RECENTLY BECAUSE THEY CAN MAKE
SOME GOOD BUSINESS DECISIONS
FOR THEMSELVES SO THE WHOLE
SYSTEM MIGHT BE SOMEWHAT ADD
ADMIRABLE.
I THINK THEY ARE REVEALING
WHAT THEY IN MANY WAYS REALLY
THINK.
IT WASN'T TOO MANY YEARS AGO
THAT WE WERE TALKING ABOUT
HARRY BELAFONTE COMMENTS ABOUT
CONDOLEEZZA RICE AND EVEN
COLIN POWELL WHEN HE SAID THEY
WERE LIVING IN THE HOUSE OF
THE MASTER.
HE WASN'T JOKING THEN.
HE MAY BE OVERSTATED A LITTLE
BIT MAYBE FOR HIM.
>> Bill: IS HE EMBOLDENED.
>> OF COURSE.
>> Bill: NOBODY CARES ABOUT
HARRY BELAFONTE.
>> THAT SONG IS IN MY HEAD
RUINING THE CHRISTMAS SEASON
BANANA BOAT.
>> Bill: SUN GOES DOWN. I LIKE
THAT SONG.
I USED HIM NOT BECAUSE HE HAS
CREDIBILITY AND THAT IS HE
SOMEBODY THAT PEOPLE LISTEN
TO, BUT TO GIVE YOU AN EXAMPLE
OF WHAT IS BEING SAID IN THE
SALONS AT THE HUFFINGTON POST.
THESE PEOPLE ARE GOING, YOU
KNOW WHAT?
IF YOU OPPOSE PRESIDENT OBAMA
NOW AND YOU OPPOSE THE SECULAR
PROGRESSIVE AGENDA WE'RE GOING
TO DEAL WITH YOU.
LOOK, THE ATTACKS ON ME, LOOK,
I HAVE A STACK OF NEWS CLIPS
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY BECAUSE
HOW DARE O'REILLY, HOW DARE HE
STAND IN OUR WAY AND POINT
THESE THINGS OUT.
WE'LL GO AFTER HIM ANY
INSTITUTION OR MEDIA SOURCE
THAT ACTUALLY EXPOSES WHAT
THEY REALLY THINK OR EVEN
QUESTIONS THEM HOW DARE YOU DO
THAT?
KANYE WEST TO BELAFONTE.
CHRISTMAS SEASON.
ANY OF THE PEOPLE WHO MIGHT
DISAGREE ON THIS THEN YOU ARE
SOMEHOW ILLEGITIMATE.
I KNOW WHAT THEY ARE DOING.
I'M NOT EVEN NECESSARILY
BLAMING THEM BECAUSE THAT'S
WHO THEY ARE.
THEY DON'T LIKE, YOU KNOW,
SOCIAL CONSERVATIVES.
THEY DON'T MUCH LIKE FISCAL
CONSERVATIVES.
THEY THINK THEY ARE SCARIER,
FRANKLY THAN AL QAEDA.
>> Bill: THEY DON'T LIKE
CHRISTIAN PEOPLE WHO SAY THIS
IS WHAT I BELIEVE AND.
>> SOCIAL CONSERVATIVE
CHRISTIANS.
THAT'S HATEFUL.
>> GAY MARRIAGE ISSUE TO ME
THAT'S NOT.
>> MOTIVATE YOUR EVERY BREATH.
>> Bill: I DON'T THINK THAT'S
GOING TO ERODE IF THE SUPREME
COURT RULES ON THE SIDE IT'S
GOING TO ERODE THE FABRIC OF
THE COUNTRY.
I UNDERSTAND WHY SOME
RELIGIOUS PEOPLE AND
TRADITIONAL AMERICANS SAY YOU
KNOW WHAT?
IT'S JUST -- IT'S NOT THE SAME
COUNTRY.
IT'S NOT WHAT WE WERE BUILT ON
HERE.
>> I DON'T THINK WHAT'S
HAPPENING NOW IS THAT THOSE
PEOPLE ARE DEMONIZED.
COMPASSIONATE THEY MIGHT HAVE
A DEEPL RELIGIOUS BELIEF
OR MORAL BELIEF THAT CONFLICTS
WITH THE POPULAR CULTURE.
LOOK, I DON'T BLAME THEM FOR
BEING VERY HEADY AND VERY
EXCITED ABOUT THEIR POLITICAL
OPPORTUNITIES BUT I CAUTION
AGAINST WHAT HAPPENED.
>> IF YOU ARE ARRESTED IN THE
MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT PLEASE
CALL HERE FIRST.
>> I WILL.
>> Bill: ME TOO.
I'M GOING TO CALL LAURA IF I'M
ARRESTED.
>> I WILL BE THERE FOR YOU.
I ALWAYS WILL BE.
>> Bill: LIKE TO YOU KNOW THAT
LAURA SIGNED A NEW RADIO DEAL
WITH OUR PAL NORM CADIS WHO
RUNS COURT SIDE ENTERTAINMENT.
HE IS MY RADIO COMMENTARY SO
LAURA IS IN GOOD HANDS.
ALSO LIKE TO YOU VOTEN IN N.
OUR BILL O'REILLY.COM POLL.
WE ASKED DO YOU BELIEVE THE
FACTOR CHRISTMAS CONTROVERSY
COVERAGE IS ACCURATE OR
OVERBLOWN.
WE WILL GIVE YOU THE RESULTS
ON MONDAY.
PLENTY MORE AS THE FACTOR
MOVES ALONG THIS EVENING.
FEMINISTS ATTACKING TAYLOR
SWIFT AND KATIE PERRY.
CULTURE WARRIORS HAVE SOME
THOUGHTS.
U.S. MARINE INCARCERATED IN
MEXICO FOR ABSOLUTELY NO
REASON AT ALL.
WE'RE ASKING THE MEXICAN
GOVERNMENT TO FREE HIM.
WE HOPE YOU STAY TUNED TO
THOSE REPEPEPEPEP
>> Bill: CULTURE WARRIOR
SEGMENT TONIGHT ALONG WITH THE
RISE OF SECULARISM IN AMERICA
MILITANT FEMINISM MAKING A
COMEBACK.
CAMILLE WROTE AN ARTICLE IN
THE HOLLYWOOD REPORTER HASHLY
CRITICIZING KATIE PERRY AND
TAYLOR SWIFT CALLING THEM
INSIPID.
SHE THINKS THEY SHOULD BE
QUOTE POWERFUL MODELS OF
MATURE BOMBINGLINESS UNQUOTE.
HERE ARE TWO LADIES WHO FIGHT
FIT THAT DESCRIPTION GRETCHEN
CARLSON AND JEANINE PIRRO.
SO WHY DON'T YOU DEFINE THE
POINT THAT MS. PAGGALA ARE
TRYING TO MAKE.
>> SHE IS SAYING THERE ARE
SUCCESSFUL WOMEN LIKE KATIE
PERRY AND TAYLOR SWIFT IN
FORBES MAGAZINE MAKE MORE
MONEY THAN JUST ABOUT ANYONE
IN TERMS OF THEIR MUSIC.
SHE IS SAYING THAT THEY ARE
INSIPID THAT THEIR MUSIC IS
BLAND AND THAT THEY ARE
MONOTONOUS AND AT THE END OF
THE DAY THEY ARE TOO BUTTONED
UP.
HER CONCERN IS THAT THEY ARE
NOT TRASHY AND THEY DON'T
REFLECT KIND OF A SENSE OF
REAL LIVING.
AND SHE TALKS ABOUT BLACK
FEMALE PERFORMERS AS STRONGER
AND MORE DEFIANT.
SHE IGNORES THE FACT THAT
PEOPLE BUY THEIR RECORDS
BECAUSE THEY LIKE MUSIC AND
SHE PREFERS WOMEN WHO
APPARENTLY IN HER MIND SHOW
MORE BODY, MORE BOSOM, MORE
BOOTY AND, THEREFORE, WE ARE
GOING BACKWARDS.
>> Bill: KATIE PERRY IS NOT
KNOWN -- DID YOU SEE IT.
>> I SAW AMAZINGLY ANGRY
FEMALE WRITING AN ARTICLE
ABOUT OTHER SUCCESSFUL WOMEN
WHO IS SHE IS PROBABLY JEALOUS
OF.
BY THE WAY BEYONCE, TAYLOR
SWIFT TO A CERTAIN DEGREE
KATIE PERRY ARE GOOD ROLE
MODELS.
>> Bill: SHE DIDN'T CRITICIZE
BEYONCE.
>> NO.
>> Bill: YOU WOULD NEVER DARE
DO THAT.
THAT WOULD BE SO
POLITICALLY -- LET'S STAY WITH
THE POINT.
TAYLOR SWIFT 23 YEARS OLD
TODAY.
I THINK SHE IS A GOOD ROLE
MODEL.
I KNOW THE FAMILY A LITTLE
BIT.
I THINK SHE TRIES TO PUT
FORTH.
KATIE PERRY I DON'T KNOW
ANYTHING ABOUT HER.
BUT PAGLIA WHO TEACHES IN
PHILADELPHIA AT SOME ARTS
COLLEGE SHE WANTS THE WOMEN TO
DO WHAT.
WHAT DOES SHE WANT.
WHAT'S THIS BOMBINGLINESS
THING WHAT.
>> TRASHY DURING THE DAY.
REMINISCENT OF THE 19 AUTOS
WHEN PEOPLE WERE COMPLACENT
AND WAITED FOR THE MEN TO COME
HOME.
>> Bill: TOO HARD TO BELIEVE
THAT SHE WANTS THEM TO BE
DRESSED?
DID YOU TAKE THAT AWAY FROM
THE ARTICLE?
>> SHE MAN PLEASING WAYS HAD
TO BE PEPPY, CHEERFUL AND
MODEST.
>> HERE IS PART OF IT.
WHO DOES SHE THINK IS A GOOD
ROLE MODEL IN THE SINGING
WORLD?
MADONNA.
>> Bill: MADONNA.
>> WHO WE JUST TALKED ABOUT A
COUPLE WEEKS AGO AS NOT BEING
A ROLE MODEL.
>> SHE STRIPPED DOWN.
SHE IS OBJECTING TO THE
CLOTHING, BILL.
SHE DOES IT OVER AND OVER
AGAIN.
>> Bill: I HAVEN'T BEEN IN
THIS FEMINIST THING.
WEREN'T FEMINIST AT ONE TIME
ANGRY ABOUT WOMEN BEING
OBJECTIFIED?
>> SEXUALIZED.
>> Bill: NOW SHE WANTS THEM TO
BE?
>> I GUESS.
>> REMEMBER WHEN WE HAD
DISCUSSIONS ABOUT THE NATIONAL
ORGANIZATION OF AMERICA WOULD
NOT LET ME IN BECAUSE I WAS A
FORMER MISS AMERICA EVEN
THOUGH I WENT TO STANFORD AND
OXFORD THEY PROBABLY WOULDN'T
BECAUSE I WAS IN WHAT THEY
DEEM A PAGEANT.
>> Bill: NOW THEY WANT YOUNGER
WOMEN TO BE MORE FLASHY AND
OBJECTIFIED?
I'M NOT GETTING ANY OF.
THIS I DIDN'T GET IT EITHER.
I WAS VERY CONFUSED.
>> MODEST AND SHE DOESN'T WANT
THEM TO BE THE PLAN,
CULTIVATED.
THIS IS MY CHRISTMASER GO THIS
-- PREMISE THERE GO THIS
IS MY CONCLUSION.
>> Bill: SHE WANTS PUBLICITY.
SHE HAS BEEN OUT OF THE
LIMELIGHT.
SHE GETS THE HOLLYWOOD
REPORTER WHICH IS NOW SOME
KIND OF LEFT WING THING TO RUN
THIS PIECE PEOPLE TALK ABOUT
IT THAT'S WHAT SHE WANTS.
IT DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE AT
ALL.
>> IT DOESN'T.
>> Bill: PERRY AND SWIFT PUT
OUT RECORDS THAT PEOPLE LIKE.
THEY HAVEN'T DONE ANYTHING
OFFENSIVE TO ME.
I HAVEN'T SEEN ANYTHING THAT
THEY HAVE DONE.
ALL THEY ARE DOING IS MAKING
AN HONEST LIVING AND NOW SHE
SAYS THEY ARE NOT
BOMBINGLINESS.
IS THERE A WORD
WOMANINGLYNESS?
>> YES.
WE WILL TAKE IT.
>> THE MAN DID NOTHING WRONG.
MEGYN KELLY ON THE CASE IN
JUST A FEW MOMENTS.
>> Bill: I'M BILL O'REILLY IN
THE KELLY FILE SEGMENT TONIGHT
WE HAVE A LOT TO TALK ABOUT
BEGINNING WITH THE TERRIBLE
ORDEAL OF 27-YEAR-OLD JOHN
HAMMER, HE IS HE A FORMER
MARINE LANCE CORPORAL IN
FLORIDA AND NOW INCARCERATED
FROM MEXICO.
MEXICANS PUT HIM IN PRISON
AFTER HE REGISTERED ANTIQUE
GUN WITH THE U.S. BORDER
PATROL.
THEN HE CROSSED INTO MEXICO.
APPARENTLY THE MEXICAN
AUTHORITIES SAW THE PAPERWORK
AND IMMEDIATELY ARRESTED
CORPORAL HAMMAR ON GUN
CHARGES.
THAT WAS FOUR MONTHS AGO AND
HE IS STILL IN PRISON.
SENATOR BILL NELSON SAID THIS.
>> BRING THIS MARINE HOME,
MEXICAN GOVERNMENT.
AND NOW THAT YOU HAVE A NEW
PRESIDENT JUST INSTALLED IN
MEXICO, THE RELATIONS WITH THE
UNITED STATES ARE ESPECIALLY
IMPORTANT TO TREAT THE UNITED
STATES CITIZENS WHO ARE
PEACEFUL IN THEIR INTENT,
INNOCENT IN THEIR OBSERVATION
OF THE MEXICAN LAWS.
>> Bill: HERE NOW AND ATTORNEY
FOX NEWS ANCHOR MEGYN KELLY
LOOKING AT THE STORY.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS, RIGHT?
>> STOTTLELY RIDICULOUS.
>> WHY DON'T THEY TURN HIM
AWAY AT THE BORDER.
>> Bill: ALL HE HAD TO DO WAS
THAT TAKING THE ANTIQUE GUN TO
COSTA RICA TO GO HUNTING.
THAT WASN'T SMART ON HIS PART.
YOU GO TO MEXICO, DON'T DO
ANYTHING, DON'T TAKE ANYTHING,
DON'T DRIVE THERE, JUST FLY,
IN GO TO YOUR RESORT HOTEL.
AND GET THE HELL OUT.
>> YOU REALLY HAVE TO THINK
DON'T BOTHER GOING UNTIL
MR. HAMMAR GETS OUT OF PRISON.
>> Bill: I DON'T THINK ANYBODY
SHOULD GO.
>> THIS GUY SERVES OUR COUNTRY
HONORABLY.
HE HAD TO GOES INTO PROST
TRAUMATIC STRESS TREATMENT.
HIS BUDDIES HAD GOTTEN KILLED
DURING SERVICE.
HE GETS OUT OF THAT AND HE
GOES JUST TO HAVE A SURFING
TRIP.
>> Bill: JUST TO GO DOWN AND
HAVE A LITTLE FUN.
>> NOT LIKE HE IS TRYING TO
PULL A FAST ONE.
REGISTERED WITH U.S. CUSTOMS
AND THOUGHT MEXICANS SAY
THAT'S IT.
YOU ARE ARE GOING TO
IMMEDIATELY TO JAIL.
HERE IS THE IRONY ABOUT IT
WHAT HAS OUR STATE DEPARTMENT
DONE?
WE HAVE MADE A FEW PHONE
CALLS.
THE PARENTS ARE VERY UPSET
THAT THE U.S. CONSULATE HASN'T
DONE MORE.
TYPICALLY THE WAY THIS WORKS
OUR STATE DEPARTMENT CALLS
THEIR STATE DEPARTMENT AND
FUNNELS DOWN THE LINE UNTIL
THEY GET TO THE STATE POLICE
AND THEY SAY DON'T BE
RIDICULOUS.
THIS ISN'T ONE OF THOSE
SITUATIONS WHERE SOMEBODY GOES
HIKING OVER AND ACCIDENTLY
CROSSES INTO IRAN.
THIS IS MEXICO.
THAT'S AN ALLY OF OURS.
WE GIVE THEM HUNDREDS OF
MILLIONS OF DOLLARS A YEAR,
BILL.
WHY ISN'T IT JUST A PHONE
CALL.
>> Bill: LET'S BE HONEST THEY
DISRESPECT US ALL THE TIME
MEXICO.
NUMBER ONE, HILLARY CLINTON
SHOULD BE INVOLVED IN THIS
HERSELF.
WE HAVEN'T SEEN ANY SIGN OF
THAT NUMBER TWO, PRESIDENT
OBAMA SHOULD BE INVOLVED WE
HAVEN'T SEEN ANY SIGN OF THAT
NUMBER THREE, THE NEW MEXICAN
PRESIDENT, THERE IS NO WAY
THAT THIS GUY SHOULDN'T LET
THIS MARINE OUT TOMORROW.
CHRISTMAS IS COMING UP.
WE CALLED THE MEXICAN EMBASSY
TODAY.
THOSE PEOPLE ARE TOTALLY
CHAOTIC.
>> THEY ARE VERY BUSY.
>> THEY DON'T KNOW WHAT THE
HELL IS GOING ON.
THEY DON'T CARE.
SO I THINK NOW WE ARE GOING TO
HAVE TO SQUEEZE.
WE WILL HAVE TO PUT PRESSURE.
>> HERE IS THE IRONY.
LET THE VIEWERS KNOW.
SO WE HAVE THIS 1.9
BILLION-DOLLAR ASSISTANCE
PROGRAM THAT WE HELP MEXICO
WITH TO FIGHT THEIR WAR ON
DRUGS, AMONG OTHER THINGS.
WE HAVE BEEN SENDING DOWN
MONEY FOR BLACKHAWK
HELICOPTERS AND SO ON.
RECENTLY OUR EFFORT HAS
SHIFTED TO MORE OF A LAW AND
ORDER ASSISTANCE PROGRAM.
AND WE HAVE HAD THE FORMER
DIRECTOR OF COLORADO'S
PENITENTIARY SYSTEM HAS
TRAINED MORE THAN 5,000
MEXICAN PRISON OFFICIALS IN
RECENT YEARS.
MEXICAN JURY LISTS RUNNING
MOCK TRIALS WITH VISITING
MEASURE JUDGES WHAT ARE THEY
TRAINING FOR?
TO TRY OUR MARINE.
IT'S RIDICULOUS.
GOING DOWN THERE TO REVAMP OUR
LAW AND ORDER SYSTEM AND WHO
ARE THEY GOING TO USE IT
AGAINST NOT THEIR OWN CARTEL
MEMBERS BUT OUR MILITARY.
>> Bill: GOING TO BE ON
HANNITY AFTER OUR PROGRAM
STICK AROUND.
WE WILL DO A STORY ON IT
TOMORROW.
MEXICAN EMBASSY, AGAIN WE
ASKED YOU ALL DAY LONG TO
COMMENT.
YOU ARE HIDING.
YOU CAN'T CONTINUE TO HIDE.
HILLARY CLINTON, YOU KNOW
WHAT?
YOU HAVE GOT TO GET INVOLVED.
ALL RIGHT, MS. SECRETARY?
THAT'S IT.
AND IF PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS TO
GET INVOLVED, HE HAS TO GET
INVOLVED.
THIS IS A MARINE CORPS PATROL.
THIS IS AN AMERICAN FOUR
MONTHS FOR NOTHING.
>> HE DIDN'T DO ANYTHING
WRONG.
>> Bill: THAT'S IT.
>> HE IS FACING UP TO 12 YEARS
IN PRISON.
ESSENTIALLY.
>> Bill: IS HE GOING TO GET
OUT SOON.
I HAVE CONFIDENCE THE NEW
PRESIDENT OF MEXICO IS GOING
TO DO THE RIGHT THING.
>> THEY ARE CALLING THE
PARENTS FROM THE JAIL AND
TRIED TO EXTORT THOUSANDS OF
DOLLARS.
>> Bill: OF COURSE, THAT'S
WHAT THEY DO.
>> HAD TO MOVE TO SOLITARY
CONFINEMENT.
THEY SAY HE HAS BEEN CHAINED
TO THE BED.
APPARENTLY WE WERE ABLE TO
STOP THAT FROM HAPPENING.
>> Bill: ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
SENATOR BOB MENENDEZ FROM NEW
JERSEY APPARENTLY HAD AN
IMMIGRANT WHO WAS IN THE
COUNTRY, AN INTERN IN THE
COUNTRY ILLEGALLY, ALL RIGHT?
>> RIGHT.
>> Bill: AND A REGISTERED SEX
OFFENDER TO BOOT.
PICK IT UP.
>> WELL, THEN, THAT INTERN
JUST GOT ARRESTED.
IS HE ONLY A YOUNG KID.
IS HE 18 YEARS OLD.
HE GOT ARRESTED.
SEX CHARGE IS AGAINST HIM?
BECAUSE IT WAS SEALED?
>> JUVY REGISTER AS A SEX
OFFENDER.
I'M CONFUSED ABOUT THIS CASE
IT HAPPENED HERE IN THE UNITED
STATES.
AND YET WHY WAS HE STILL HERE?
>> Bill: BECAUSE THEY DON'T
DEPORT PEOPLE.
YOU KNOW.
>> THEY ILLEGAL IMMIGRANT
REGISTER AS SEX OFFENDER AND
GET A JOB IN THE SENATOR'S
OFFICE.
>> Bill: TOMORROW ON THE
FACTOR "BOSTON GLOBE" BIG
INVESTIGATION ON ILLEGAL
IMMIGRANTS COMMITTING
HORRENDOUS CRIMES AND NOTHING
HAPPENS TO THEM WE'LL HAVE
THAT TOMORROW.
YOU SHOULDN'T BE SURPRISED
ABOUT THIS.
HAVE YOU SEEN THIS BEFORE.
WHAT ABOUT MENENDEZ.
>> THE ALLEGATION IS THE
ASSOCIATED PRESS CLAIMS ONE
U.S. OFFICIAL FAMILIAR WITH
THE CASE WHO IS TELLING THE
A.P. THAT ICE SNUFFED OUT THE
GUY, WENT TO THE DEPARTMENT OF
HOMELAND SECURITY AND SAID
THIS IS GOING TO BE A HIGH
PROFILE THING BECAUSE IS HE
GOING TO BE INTERN FOR
SENATOR.
THIS OFFICIAL CLAIMS THAT
HOMELAND SECURITY TOLD ICE
DON'T MAKE THE AS UNTIL AFTER
THE ELECTION.
ICE AND HOMELAND SECURITY ARE
DENYING THAT CATEGORICALLY ON
THE RECORD.
THEY CLAIM NO POLITICS WERE
INVOLVED IN THIS.
AND THEY JUST MADE THE ARREST.
MENENDEZ.
>> Bill: WHAT DOES HE SAY.
>> MENENDEZ SAID I WAS
SHOCKED.
I JUST FOUND THIS OUT.
HIS OFFICE IS SAYING LOOK WE
COULDN'T HAVE KNOWN HE WAS
ILLEGAL IMMIGRANT BECAUSE HOW
WOULD WE HAVE CHECKED THAT?
>> Bill: WHEN YOU ARE INTERN
ARE YOU SUPPOSED TO CHECK THE
RESUMES AND STUFF AND FIGURE
OUT WHERE HE COMES FROM?
>> IT'S THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT
OR LIKE I KNOW HE WAS UNPAID
INTERN.
>> WRITE A CHECK ON HIM.
WRITE A LITTLE CHECK AND SEE
WHERE THAT IS OFFICE ON
CAPITOL HILL RIGHT NOW.
>> Bill: KEEP YOUR EYE ON THIS
MARINE, RIGHT?
>> HIS PARENTS ARE GOING TO BE
ON "AMERICA LIVE" TOO.
>> Bill: WE ARE GOING TO HOLD
THE PRESIDENT, SECRETARY OF
STATE, AND THE PRESIDENT OF
MEXICO ACCOUNTABLE FOR.
THIS THEY CAN GET HIM OUT
TOMORROW.
BAWRTS WORLD ON WATTERS WORLD
ON DECK.
HOW MUCH DO THE FOLKS KNOW
ABOUT THE INTENSE DEBATE IN
>> Bill: BACK OF THE BOOK
SEGMENT TONIGHT, WATTERS
WORLDS YOU A MAY KNOW THE
PINHEADS IN WASHINGTON CAN'T
GET A BUDGET DEAL DONE.
EVERYBODY'S TAXES MIGHT GO UP
JANUARY 1st AND SEVERE CUTS
TO FEDERAL PROGRAMS MIGHT KICK
IN AS WELL.
THE DEBATE HAS BEEN FRAMED AS
A FISCAL CLIFF BUT THAT'S A
CLICHE THE REAL ISSUE IS
FAIRLY COMPLICATED MAC HE CROW
ECONOMICS.
WE ASKED JESSE WATTERS TO FIND
OUT WHAT THE FOLKS FIND OUT
ABOUT IT
♪ FREE FALLING.
>> THIS FISCAL CLIFF I KEEP
HEARING ABOUT, WHERE IS THIS
CLIFF?
>> I ABSOLUTELY HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT YOU ARE TALKING ABOUT.
>> CONGRESS.
>> I HAVE NO IDEA.
I DON'T KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT
POLITICS.
>> BALTIMORE.
I DON'T KNOW.
>> I THINK IT'S RELATED TO THE
APOCK CLIPS.
>> DO YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENS
OVER F. WE GO OVER THE CLIFF.
>> YES OUR TAXES GO UP.
>> MILITARY STARTS LOSING
MONEY.
>> YOU ARE FINE WITH THAT.
>> I'M FINE WITH THAT WE SPEND
A LOT OF MONEY ON THE
MILITARY.
>> DEFINE THE FISCAL CLIFF FOR
ME.
>> IMAGINARY CLIFF SOMEWHERE
IN MY MIND THAT WE ARE ALL
GOING TO JUMP OFF OF.
>> YOU MEAN THE END OF THE
WORLD TYPE OF THING?
>> WELL, NOT REALLY.
[ LAUGHTER ]
♪ AND I FALL TO PIECES.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA AND HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER
REPRESENTED CREATE THIS FISCAL
CLIFF.
IF THEY DON'T GET A LONG-TERM
BUDGET DEAL DONE BY
JANUARY 2ND, 2013, MASSIVE
AUTOMATIC SPENDING CUTS ARE
TRIGGERED.
NOW, DO YOU KNOW WHAT THE
PRESIDENT'S PLAN IS TO ADDRESS
THIS CLIFF?
>> HE SAYS HE WANTS TO RAISE
TAXES ON ALL THE RICH PEOPLE.
>> EVERY TIME IT COMES ON THE
RADIO, OR THE NEWS, I TURN IT
OFF.
>> RAISE TAXES ON THE RICH,
WHICH I THINK WILL FUND
GOVERNMENT FOR LIKE A WEEK.
>> ARE YOU WORRIED ABOUT YOUR
TAXES GOING UP.
>> NO.
I ACTUALLY HOPE THE FISCAL
CLIFF HAPPENS.
>> WHAT?
>> PUSH IT OFF THE CLIFF.
LET'S DO IT.
>> DO YOU KNOW WHO JOHN
BOEHNER IS.
>> NO.
>> HE IS A TAN GUY THAT CRIES
A LOT.
>> HE CRIES A LOT.
>> HE CRIES A LOT?
>> YES, HE DOES.
>> POOR THING.
>> SPEAKER OF THE HOUSE.
>> DO YOU KNOW WHO JOHN
BOEHNER IS.
>> MY BEST FRIEND.
>> I HAVE SEEN HIM WE USE THE
SAME TANNING BED.
>> THE FISCAL CLIFF?
>> YES.
>> ARE YOU AFRAID?
>> I'M VERY WORRIED, YES,
INDEED.
>> I'M SCARED OF HEIGHTS
THOUGH.
>> ARE YOU NERVOUS?
>> I THINK YOU ARE MAKING ME
NERVOUS.
[ LAUGHTER ]
♪ FEELS LIKE I'M FALLING FOR
THE FIRST TIME.
>> JUST A DAY BEFORE THE
PAINFUL SPENDING CUTS TAKE
PLACE THE BUSH TAX CUTS
EXPIRE.
THAT'S WHY THEY CALL IT THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WANTS TO LET
THOSE TAXES GO UP ON THE
SO-CALLED RICH.
GENERATING $80 BILLION IN
REVENUE.
THAT'S JUST 8 DAYS OF FEDERAL
SPENDING.
LESS THAN 1 PERCENT OF OUR 16
TRILLION-DOLLAR DEBT.
DO YOU KNOW HOW MUCH DEBT
AMERICA IS IN RIGHT NOW?
>> LIKE BILLIONS LIKE
$14 BILLION OR SOMETHING LIKE
THAT?
DO YOU KNOW WHAT OUR NATIONAL
DEBT IS RIGHT NOW?
>> NO IDEA.
>> I'M GOING TO SAY 30
SOMETHING TRILLION.
>> WHOA.
>> WE'RE AT 16 TRILLION.
YOU JUST DOUBLED IT.
ARE YOU A FACTOR FAN BY ANY
CHANCE?
>> I LOVE YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> AND I LOVE HIM.
BUT I'M TOO CHEAP FOR CABLE.
>> HOW ARE YOU?
I WATCH YOU ALMOST EVERY DAY.
>> I DON'T AGREE WITH A LOT OF
HIS COMMENTARY.
>> REALLY?
WHAT SPECIFICALLY?
>> I HAVE BEEN OUT OF THE
COUNTRY FOR TWO YEARS.
I'M NOT A GOOD PERSON TO ACT.
>> LET ME GUESS YOU LIVE IN
FRANCE.
>> HOW DID YOU KNOW?
>> OH, NAILED IT.
>> Bill: SO YOU ARE ROAMING
AROUND DC I ALWAYS ASK THIS
QUESTION BUT IT'S INTERESTING
TO ME.
YOU TALK TO, WHAT, A COUPLE OF
DOZEN PEOPLE.
>> ABOUT TWO DOZEN.
SO, WHAT PERCENTAGE OF THEM
HAD ANY CLUE AT ALL WHAT'S AT
STAKE HERE?
>> I SAY HALF OF THEM CLUELESS
ON THE CLIFF.
>> HALF OF THEM NO IDEA.
>> IT'S BORING.
THEY ARE TALKING ABOUT
TRILLIONS OF DOLLARS.
THEY DO THIS MAN WHO CRIED
WOLF ALL THE TIME.
THEY HAVE THESE CLIFFS WITH
THE DEBT CEILING WITH THE BUSH
TAX CUSS.
PEOPLE ARE NUMB TO THIS.
THEY DO THIS EVERY CHRISTMAS.
THEY DON'T CARE.
>> LOOK, NUMBER ONE WHEN YOU
SAY 16 TRILLION-DOLLAR DEBT IT
DOESN'T MEAN ANYTHING TO
ANYBODY.
>> YOU CAN'T WRAP YOUR HEAD
AROUND THAT.
>> Bill: MAKE YOUR CAR PAYMENT
TAKE YOUR CAR AWAY THEY KNOW.
NUMBER TWO, IT'S A PRETTY
COMPLICATED SITUATION.
IT'S NOT JUST RAISING THE
TAXES ON WEALTHY AND
CORPORATIONS.
IT'S A LOT OF OTHER STUFF
INVOLVED IN IT AS WELL.
BUT, OUT OF THE TWO DOZEN
PEOPLE, WERE THERE ANYBODY --
WAS THERE ONE PERSON WHO
REALLY HAD A HANDLE ON IT?
>> WELL, WE RAN INTO AN ACTUAL
PERSON WHO WORKS FOR A
SENATOR.
AND THAT WAS -- THAT MADE THE
PACKAGE BECAUSE, WITHOUT HER,
NO ONE WOULD HAVE KNOWN WHAT'S
GOING ON.
>> Bill: SO ONE OUT OF 24.
>> ONE OUT OF 20 NAILED IT.
FACTOR FAN AND SAID SHE LOVED
ME.
>> Bill: YOU CAN'T HAVE
EVERYTHING.
JESSE WATTERS, EVERYBODY,
THERE HE IS.
IS HE GOING TO HAWAII.
WATTERS IS GOING TO HAWAII
BECAUSE THE PRESIDENT IS
VACATIONING THERE I'M SURE THE
PRESIDENT IS GOING TO INVITE
YOU.
YOU WILL BE OUT AND WACKY
TOGETHER.
>> ALOHA.
>> FACTOR TIP OF THE DAY
HISTORIC OCCURRENCE IN THE
BOOK WORLD THAT YOU SHOULD
KNOW ABOUT.
THE TIP 60 SECONDS AWAY.
>> FACTOR TIP OF THE DAY.
IT IS AN AMAZING SITUATION.
TAKE A LOOK AT THE FULL-PAGE AD
IN THE NEW YORK TIMES,
CELEBRATING THE FACT THAT
"KILLING KENNEDY" IS THE
NUMBER-1 SELLING BOOK.
"KILLING LINCOLN," NUMBER 2,
AFTER 60 WEEKS IN THE
MARKETPLACE.
THAT HAS NEVER HAPPENED BEFORE,
AS FAR AS WE KNOW.
THE "KILLING KEN DE" AUDIOBOOK.
NUMBER 1.
INCREDIBLE.
THANK YOU ALL.
NOW TO THE MAIL...
>> DISTANT MAKE ME SLANT STORY,
THERE IS NO EXCUSE FOR IT.
>> I WANT IT HEAR THE OPPOSING
POINTS OF VIEW, BILL.
IT'S BORING TO JUST HEAR ONE
SIDE, WHICH IS WHY WE MAINTAIN
OUR NUMBER-1 STATUS ON THE
FACTOR.
WE EMBRACE BOTH SIDES OF THE
DEBATE.