information kit with DVD,
brochure and price list.
Call right now and you'll
also receive a $50 savings
card just for inquiring
about the Sleep Number bed.
Ask about our Risk-Free
30-night in-home trial.
Call now for your FREE
information kit and a FREE
$50 savings card.
Call now!
>> A MINISTER SAID TODAY ABOUT
SCHOOL SHOOTINGS IN CONNECTICUT,
THESE ARE PATTERNS OF GRIEF WE
HAVE REHERRED TOO MANY TIMES
BEFORE, WE KNOW HOW TO GATHER
THE CANDLES AND THIS IS
DIFFERENT, AFTER WHAT HAPPENED
IN THAT TOWN.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL BE
PERSONALLY DELIVERING THE
THOUGHTS AND PRAYERS ON BEHALF
OF THE NATION TO A COMMUNITY
REELING FROM AN UNTHINKABLE
CRIME.
RIGHT NOW HE IS MEETING WITH
VICTIMS' FAMILIES AND FIRST
RESPONDERS AS YOU LOOK AT HALL
BEFORE PARTICIPATING IN A VIGIL
TO REMEMBER THE 26 VICTIMS,
MASSACRED INSIDE AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
MOST OF THEM CHILDREN, NO OLDER
THAN SEVEN.
THE FIRST FUNERAL FOR ONE OF THE
SEVEN-YEAR-OLDS, WILL BE HELD
TOMORROW.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US FOR
SPECIAL COVERAGE OF THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THE PRESIDENT IS EXPECTED TO
SPEAK AND WILL OFFER MOURNERS
WORDS OF COMFORT.
ED HENRY IS LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
JUST OUTSIDE.
TELL US MORE OF WHAT THE
PRESIDENT IS DOING THERE RIGHT
NOW.
>>Reporter: A SOFT RAIN IS
FALLING, THE PRESIDENT IS IN THE
HIGH SCHOOL BEHIND ME THROUGH
THE TREES.
HE IS MEETING WITH THE FAMILIES.
THEY HAVE BEEN THROUGH SUCH A
TRAUMATIC COUPLE OF DAYS.
YET DESPITE THE TEMPERATURES,
DESPITE THE DIFFICULTIES, PEOPLE
HAVE BEEN LINING UP WAITING TO
GET INTO THE HIGH SCHOOL FOR THE
RARE PRAYER VIGIL.
THE RED CROSS IS GIVING OUT
TEDDY BEARS TO CHILDREN AND
GIVING OWN BLANKETS TO PEOPLE
WHO ARE FRIGID IN NEWTOWN.
THEY NEED WARMTH GIVEN WHAT THEY
HAVE BEEN THROUGH.
I SPOKE TO A MAN WHO KNEW TWO
PEOPLE WHO WORKED AT THE SCHOOL,
A TEACHER AND THE PRINCIPAL WE
HEARD SO MUCH ABOUT FIGHTING TO
SAVE OTHERS.
HE KNEW TWO KILLED AND HE KNEW A
CHILD WHO LIVED.
WE HAVE TO REMEMBER THE FOLKS
WHO LIVED ARE TRAUMAIZED, WHO
HEARD AND SAW SOME OF THE
SHOOTING, GOING THROUGH A TOUGH
TIME.
IT HAS BEEN PERSONAL FOR THE
PRESIDENT, AS WELL, HE WAS
FIGHTING BACK TEARS ON FRIDAY.
HE SAID HE IS NOT JUST PRESIDENT
BUT A PARENT, AS WELL, AND HE IS
MEETING WITH SOME OF FAMILY
MEMBERS OF VICTIMS AND HE MEET
WITH FIRST RESPONDERS.
HE WILL THANK THEM FOR THEIR
HEROIC EFFORTS AT THE CRIME
SCENE AND WHAT THEY HAVE DONE TO
HELP HEAL THE COMMUNITY.
THE PRESIDENT WILL MAKE SOME
REMARKS.
WE ARE TOLD BY HIS AIDES THE
PRESIDENT WROTE MOST OF THIS
SPEECH.
HE WAS DOING SOME REWRITES ON
AIR FORCE ONE ON THE WAY TO
CONNECTICUT.
HE WILL MAKE IT PERSONAL AND
FROM THE HEART.
>>Bret: WE HAVE HEARD
POLITICIANS TALKING ABOUT GUN
CONTROL ON SUNDAY SHOWS.
WE HAVE HEARD ABOUT A LOST
POLICY PRESCRIPTIONS HERE IN
WASHINGTON.
DO YOU THINK THE PRESIDENT WILL
GET INTO POLICY TALK AT ALL IN
THIS SPEECH TONIGHT?
>>Reporter: THE SCIENCE I HAVE
IS HE WILL STEER CLEAR OF POLICY
TALK WHETHER IT IS GUN CRIMINAL
OR HOW WE DEAL AND TREAT PEOPLE
WITH MENTAL ILLNESSES IN THIS
COUNTRY WHICH IS AN IMPORTANT
ISSUE THAT HAS POPPED UP.
HE WILL AVOID THAT TONIGHT.
AS YOU MENTIONED, THE MAYOR
BLOOMBERG FROM NEW YORK CITY WAS
ON A SUNDAY SHOW TODAY PUSHING
THE PRESIDENT HARD SAYING HE
OWES THE AMERICAN PEOPLE, AND
REPUBLICANS ARE SAYING SECOND
AMENDMENT IS A CHERISHED RIGHT.
THE BOTTOM LINE FROM THE WHITE
HOUSE AIDES IS THE PRESIDENT
DOESN'T THINK THIS IS THE TIME
OR PLACE, TONIGHT, AND HE KNOWS
THERE WILL AN GREAT DEBATE IN
THE DAYS AHEAD.
HE SET HIGH EXPECTATION ON
FRIDAY WHEN HE SAID HE WANTS
MEANINGFUL ACT AND HE WILL FACE
PRESSURE TO FOLLOW THROUGH ON
THAT BUT TONIGHT THE AIDES SAY
THIS IS ABOUT PRAYERS.
>>Bret: HE HAS DONE THIS
BEFORE.
HE HAS HAD PRACTICE.
>>Reporter: ABSOLUTELY.
IN TUCSON, HE GAVE REPORTS FOR
REPUBLICANS AND DEMOCRATS AND
INDEPENDENTS SAYING HE SPOKE FOR
AN ENTIRE NATION.
IT WASN'T JUST SPEAKING FOR
DEMOCRATS.
SAME AFTER AURORA HE MET THE
VICTIMS IN THE HOSPITAL, FOLKS
WHO SURVIVED THAT SHOOTING AT
THE MOVIE THEATER.
AGAIN, HE IS GOING THROUGH THIS
AND THAT IS WHY HE WILL FACE
TREASURE IN THE SECOND TERM TO
ACT.
>>Bret: THANK YOU, ED.
26 LIVES WERE TAKEN INSIDE THE
SCHOOL.
EACH OF THEM, OF COURSE, YOUNG
AND BEAUTIFUL.
WE LEARN ABOUT THE CHILDREN WHO
BROUGHT SMILES AND LIT UP ROOMS
AND THE ADULT, A TEACHER WHO
DIED TRYING TO SHIELD HER
STUDENTS FROM GUNFIRE.
AND OTHERS WHOSE ACTIONS LIKELY
SAVED LIKES.
THE UNFATHOMABLE LOSS FELT FAR
BEYOND NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
COMPLETE STRANGERS COMING FROM
ACROSS THE COUNTRY TO OFFER
THEIR SUPPORT AND CONDOLENCES.
>> COULD NOT SLEEP LAST NIGHT
TURN ON THE NEWS, THAT MATTER
THE CHANNEL IT IS ON.
THE LEAST I CAN DO WITH THE
HOLIDAYS APPROACHING.
MOLLY LINE IS LIVE IN NEWTOWN
WITH MORE.
MOLLY, WHAT ARE WE LEARNING?
>>Reporter: WE ARE SEEING THE
FACES TO MATCH WITH THE 20 NAMES
OF THE CHILDREN.
ONE PICTURE WE HAVE TODAY, JACK
PINTO A HUGE GIANT FAN, SIX, IN
1st GRADE.
HE LOVES SPORTS AND HE IS
HONORED TONIGHT BY ONE OF HIS
FAVORITE PLAYERS, VICTOR CRUZ, A
GIANTS PLAYER, OF COURSE, WRITE
ON HIS GLOVES TODAY.
AND OLIVIA JUST SIX YEARS OLD,
FAMILY FRIENDS CREATED A
MEMORIAL FUND ON FACEBOOK,
FILLED WITH CHRISTMAS-THEMED
PHOTOS.
>>Bret: THESE ARE ALL TOUGH TO
GO THROUGH.
EN FAMILIES WHO SURVIVED THE
INCIDENT ARE SUFFERING, OBVIOUS
LY.
>> CHRIS WALLACE THIS MORNING
HAD A CHANCE TO SPEAK WITH A
FATHER WHOSE CHILD SURVIVED THE
MASSACRE.
AND HIS SON WAS INSIDE WHEN THE
GUNMAN CAME IN A CLASSROOM AND
SHOT THE LITTLE BOY'S TEACHER.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> THE CHILDREN WITNESSED THE
SHOOTER COME TO THE ROOM, SHOOT
THE TEACHER AND CONTINUE FIRING,
THE CHILDREN ACTED ON INSTINCT
AND WHAT THEY WERE TAUGHT WHICH
WAS TO RUN AND THEY DID.
THEY RAN TO THE MAIN ROAD 100
YARDS AWAY.
MY SON AND SEVERAL OF THE OTHER
STUDENTS WERE EXTREMELY BRAVE IN
WHAT THEY DID.
>>Reporter: SO MANY PARENTS
HAVE THE RELIEF IF THEIR CHILD
MADE IT HOME BUT IT IS
BITTERSWEET BECAUSE OTHER
PARENTS ARE SUFFERING SO GREAT
GREATLY.
>>Bret: THANK YOU, MOLLY.
AS THE COMMUNITY STRUGGLES TO
DEVELOP, STORIES OF HEROICKISM
ARE STARTING TO EMERGE,
INCLUDING THAT OF SCHOOL
PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG,
LURCHING AT THE SHOOTER.
ONE OF THE PRINCIPAL'S FRIENDS
IS NOT SURPRISED, BECAUSE SHE
TRAINED IF A SITUATION SIMILAR
TO WHAT UNFOLDED.
>> SHE KNEW THE HEALTH AND
SAFETY OF HER CHILDREN WERE
PARAMOUNT.
SHE ACTUALLY SAVED A GREAT MANY
LIVES BY TAKING HER ACTION.
THE SHOOTER HAD THE CAPABILITY
OF SHOOTING MORE AND THE TRAGEDY
WOULD HAVE BEEN FAR WORSE IF NOT
FOR HER HOUR -- REACTIONS.
WE DID NOT THINK THIS WOULD
BECOME REALITY.
SHE IS TRULY A HERO TODAY.
>>Gregg: WE HEAR THAT
PRINCIPAL HOCHSPRUNG IMPLEMENTED
NEW SECURITY MEASURES AT THE
SCHOOL INCLUDING CHECKING THE
I.D. OF VISITORS NOT RECOGNIZED
BY STAFF.
NOW OUR PANEL WHO WILL BE WITH
US THROUGHOUT THE EVENING,
SENIOR WRITER FOR THE WEEKLY
STANDARD, STEVEN HAYES, AND NINA
AND CHARLES KRAUTHAMMER.
THESE ARE TOUGH TO LISTEN TO.
CHARLES, WE HAVE LISTENED TO
THIS A FEW DAYS AND THIS IS THE
CHALLENGE OF THE PRESIDENT AS HE
IS READY FOR THE RARE SERVICE.
ANY THOUGHTS?
>>Reporter: YOU HAVE A HUMAN
TRAGEDY AND THE FAMILY
TRAGEDIES, COMMUNITY TRAGEDY AND
THEN A NATIONAL TRAGEDY BECAUSE
OF THE WAY THE NEWS IS SPREAD.
THE PRESIDENT'S ROLE IS TO TRY
TO CRYSTALLIZE THAT.
I AM GLAD TO HEAR FROM ED HENRY
THIS IS NOT A TIME TO SPEAK
ABOUT POLITICS.
THERE IS SOMETHING OBSCENE ABOUT
JUMPING IN AT A TIME OF GREAT
NATIONAL GRIEF AND IN SOME WAYS
DISORIENTATION WITH A PROGRAM OF
POLITICAL ACTION BEFORE THE DEAD
ARE EVEN INTERRED.
SOME DECENCY REQUIRES PEOPLE
SHOULD AT LEAST STEP BACK, WAIT
FOR THE EMOTIONS TO PASS, NOT
THAT YOU CAN'T DO ANALYSIS AND
TRY TO THINK THROUGH WHAT IS
BEHIND WHAT MIGHT HAVE
CONTRIBUTED, BUT, BEFORE PEOPLE
ENACT AGENDAS THEY SHOULD ALLOW
THE MOURNING TO TAKE PLACE.
>> THIS IS, REALLY, A
CONSOLER-IN-CHIEF ROLE FOR
PRESIDENT OBAMA.
THAT COMMUNITY...WE HAVE JUST
SCRATCHED THE SURFACE OF SOME OF
THE STORIES AND JUST SEEING THE
PICTURES.
>>Guest: HE IS PARENT IN CHIEF
TONIGHT.
I HAVE A CHILD IN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AND I GOT A CALL A FEW
DAYS AGO AND IT WAS A LOCKDOWN
DRILL, THEY DO A RECORDED CALL
AND CALL BACK AND TELL YOU IT IS
A DRILL.
A COUPLE OF DAYS LATER, WINTER
CONCERT, CHRISTMAS CONCERT, AND
AFTER, THE PRINCIPAL SAID TO ALL
OF US PARENTS GATHERED, THESE
WERE PRE-K AND KINDERGARTEN, I
WANT TO THANK YOU FOR ENTRUSTING
YOUR CHILDREN TO US.
TWO HOURS LATER I HEAR THE NEWS
AND ALL OF THE WORDS TOOK ON
MORE MEANING, MORE HORRIFIC
MEANING THAN YOU COULD IMAGINE.
NOW THE PRESIDENT IS
CONSOLER-IN-CHIEF, PARENT IN
CHIEF, BUT AT SOME POINT WHEN
YOU LOOK AT SIX-YEAR-OLD BODIES
RIDDLED WITH MULTIPLE BULLETS WE
HAVE TO START LOOKING FOR WAYS
TO TAKE THE WORD "MASS" OUT OF
MASS MURDER.
I HOPE HE WILL MOVE FORWARD TO
DO SOME SORT OF INDEPENDENT
COMMISSION THAT HAS THE URGENCY
WE HAD AFTER 9/11.
>> THIS IS UNBELIEVABLE SENSE
WHEN YOU THINK OF ED HENRY
TALKING ABOUT AURORA, TUCSON,
AND THIS KEEPS HAPPENING BUT
THIS SITUATION IS DIFFERENT AND
SO MUCH WORSE BECAUSE OF WHAT WE
ARE SEEING, THE PICTURES OF THE
INNOCENT HELPLESS CHILDREN.
I HAVE A SIX-YEAR OLD NIECE, MY
BROTHER IS A TEACHER, YOU LOOK
AT THESE SITUATIONS AND IT IS
JUST SO HORRIFYING AND YOU
WONDER HOW PEOPLE CAN COVER FROM
IT.
THE PRESIDENT, I DON'T ENVY HIM
TO HAVE TO COME BEFORE THESE
PEOPLE AND GIVE THEM SOME SORT
OF CONSOLATION TO BE ABLE TO
MOVE ON.
>>Bret: THERE IS SO MUCH WE
DON'T KNOW, WE DON'T EVEN KNOW
THIS SHOOTER'S CONNECTION TO THE
SCHOOL.
WE DON'T KNOW THE MOTHER'S
CONNECTION AND SHE IS A VICTIM.
SHE IS THE 27th VICTIM.
THERE IS SO MUCH WE DON'T KNOW.
>> IT IS A REASON THAT SO MUCH
OF THE DISCUSSION OVER THE
WEEKEND AND IN SOME SENSE THE
POLITICIZING OF THIS IS
REGRETTABLE.
IF YOU GO BACK AND PICK UP ON
WHAT THE OTHERS HAVE SAID, YOU
LOOK AT THE PRESIDENT'S ROLE,
AND SOMEONE WHO DOES NOT AGREE
WITH THE PRESIDENT VERY OFTEN ON
POLICY, WHAT THE PRESIDENT HAS
DONE WELL IS GIVEN SPEECHES AND
BRINGING PEOPLE TOGETHER IN
TIMES LIKE THIS.
I STILL THINK THE SPEECH HE GAVE
FOR THE MEMORIAL FOR GABRIELLE
GIFFORDS WAS THE BET SPEECH --
BEST SPEECH OF HIS PRESIDENCY
AND IT TOOK COURAGE TO AVOID THE
PRESSURE TO GET POLITICAL
QUICKLY.
LIKE CHARLES SAID I AM GLAD TO
HEAR IT SOUNDS LIKE HE WILL NOT
DO THAT.
IT IS FINE TO HAVE A COMMISSION
AND LOOK INTO THIS.
IF WE DIDN'T AS A NATION ASK
TOUGH QUESTIONS AFTER AN EVENTS
LIKE THIS I DON'T THINK WE WOULD
BE MUCH OF A NATION.
YOU HAVE TO HAVE THOSE
DISCUSSIONS.
I HOPE HE DOES WHAT HE HAS DONE
IN THE PAST AND PLAY THE ROLE AS
CONSOLER-IN-CHIEF AND TALK TO
THOSE WHO ARE GRIEVING IN THE
COMMUNITY AND THE NATION.
WE ARE ALL TELLING PERSONAL
STORIES AND EVERYONE YOU TALK TO
HAS A STORY OR A CONNECTION OR A
WAY TO IDENTIFY WITH THIS.
>>Bret: EVERY SINGLE PERSON
HAS REACTED IN THE WAY WE HAVE
BEEN TALKING ABOUT.
WE ARE AWAITING PRESIDENT
OBAMA'S REMARKS AND A SERVICE
AND A PRAYER VIGIL THERE FOR THE
VICTIMS OF THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
NEXT, POLICE RELEASE NEW DETAILS
WHAT THEY FOUND IN THEIR
INVESTIGATION.
Sometimes what we suffer from
Is bigger than we think ...
like the flu.
With aches, fever and chills-
the flu's a really big deal.
So why treat it like
it's a little cold?
There's something
that works differently
than over-the-counter
remedies.
Prescription TAMIFLU attacks
the flu virus at its source.
So don't wait. Call your
doctor right away.
TAMIFLU is prescription
medicine for treating the flu
in adults and children
one year and older
whose flu symptoms started
within the last two days.
Before taking TAMIFLU tell your
doctor if you're pregnant,
nursing. have serious
health conditions,
or take other medicines.
If you develop an allergic
reaction, a severe rash,
or signs of unusual behavior,
stop taking TAMIFLU and call
your doctor immediately.
Children and adolescents in
particular may be at an
increased risk
of seizures, confusion
or abnormal behavior.
The most common
side effects are
mild to moderate nausea
and vomiting.
The flu comes on fast,
so ask your
doctor about TAMIFLU.
Prescription for flu.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT STARTED LONG AGO.
THE JOY OF GIVING SOMETHING
EVERYTHING YOU'VE GOT.
IT TAKES PASSION.
AND IT'S NOT LETTING UP
ANYTIME SOON.
AT UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company,
WE UNDERSTAND THAT COMMITMENT.
AND ALWAYS HAVE.
SO DOES AARP,
AN ORGANIZATION
SERVING THE NEEDS
OF AMERICANS 50 AND OVER
FOR GENERATIONS.
SO IT'S NO SURPRISE
MILLIONS HAVE CHOSEN
AN AARP Medicare Supplement
Insurance Plan,
INSURED BY UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company.
LIKE ALL STANDARDIZED
MEDICARE SUPPLEMENT PLANS,
THEY HELP COVER
SOME OF THE EXPENSES
MEDICARE DOESN'T PAY.
AND SAVE YOU UP TO THOUSANDS
IN OUT-OF-POCKET COSTS.
TO FIND OUT MORE,
REQUEST YOUR
FREE DECISION GUIDE.
CALL OR GO ONLINE TODAY.
AFTER ALL,
WHEN YOU'RE GOING THE DISTANCE,
IT'S NICE TO HAVE
THE EXPERIENCE AND COMMITMENT
TO GO ALONG WITH YOU.
KEEP DREAMING. KEEP DOING.
GO LONG.
>>Bret: AS YOU
LOOK LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, PEOPLE ARE FILING
IN FOR THE PRAYER SERVICE.
WE TOLD BY THE WHITE HOUSE POOL,
THE PRESIDENT NOW IS MEETING
WITH FAMILIES DEVASTATED BY THE
TRAGEDY.
ONE BY ONE, A MEETING, MEETING
WITH THE FAMILIES IN THE CHOOSE
ROOM, MEETING INDIVIDUALLY WITH
THE VICTIMS' FAMILIES AND
MEETING WITH FIRST RESPONDERS.
WE ARE STILL LEARNING NEW
DETAILS ABOUT THE MASSACRE.
POLICE ARE REVEALING THE GUNMAN
SHOT HIS OWN MOTHER MULTIPLE
TIME IN THE HEAD BEFORE HEADING
TO SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
KILLING 26 OTHERS AND THEN
HIMSELF.
>> THE FEMALE FOUND AT THE
SECONDARY SCENE LOCATION IN
NEWTOWN, IS POSITIVELY
IDENTIFIED AS NANCY LANZA WITH
THE DEATH RULED A HOMICIDE.
THE MAIL SUSPECT IDENTIFIED AS
THE SHOOTER HAS BEEN POSITIVELY
IDENTIFIED AS ADAM LANZA HE
RESIDED AT THAT RESIDENCE.
THE CAUSE OF DEATH IS RULED A
SUICIDE BY GUNSHOT.
>>Bret: MIKE, SO, NOW, WE KNOW
THE SHOOTER HAD FOUR WEAPONS?
REPORT VERY FOUR WEAPONS AND
HUNDREDS ROUNDS OF AMMUNITION,
HUNDREDS WERE FIRED AND HUNDREDS
WERE CARRIED.
THE PRIMARY WEAPON WAS A ASSAULT
RIFLE COUPLED WITH HIGH-CAPACITY
30-ROUND CLIPS.
HE CARRIED TWO SIDE ARMS, BUT A
.9 MILLIMETER AND ANOTHER WAS A
FLOCK.
ONE WAS USED AS THE FIRST
RESPONDERS WERE APPROACHING TO
KILL HIMSELF WITH A SINGLE
GUNSHOT TO THE HEAD.
THERE WAS A FOURTH WEAPON, A
SHOTGUN, ACCORDING TO POLICE AND
IT WAS LEFT IN THE CAR.
ALL OF THE WEAPONS ARE GOING TO
BE KEY TO THE INVESTIGATION.
>> THE WEAPONRY IS GOING TO
COMPLETELY EXAMINED IN THE
LABORATORY.
IT WILL BE HISTORICALLY SEARCHED
SO WE CAN ATTEMPT TO DETERMINE
EVERY PATH THE WEAPONS TOOK
SINCE THEY WERE MANUFACTURED
EVERY TIME THEY WERE USED WITH
AS MUCH INFORMATION AS POSSIBLE
WE CAN OBTAIN RELATIVE TO EACH
WEAPON.
>> WE KNOW BEST ATTACK HE KILLED
HIS MOTHER LAYING IN BEDS FOUR
GUNSHOT WOUNDS TO THE HEAD.
SHE WAS STILL IN HER NIGHT
CLOTHES.
>>Bret: I MENTIONED THIS WITH
STEVE HAZE, THE FACT THAT
OFFICIALS THOUGHT THE MOTHER MAY
IS WORKED AT THE SCHOOL AND THAT
WAS THE CONNECTION.
NOW THEY SAY THAT IS NOT THE
CASE.
WE STILL DON'T REALLY KNOW, DO
WE, THE CONNECTION BETWEEN ADAM
LANZA AND THIS SCHOOL, DO WE?
>>Guest: IT IS STILL A
MYSTERY.
THE EARLY INFORMATION SHE WAS
POSSIBLY A TEACHER OR SUBSTITUTE
TEACHER WAS FALSE.
ARTICLES NOW SUGGEST SHE
VOLUNTEERED AS A TEACHER'S AIDE.
UNPROVEN AND UNCONFIRMED.
WE KNOW FROM HER SISTER IN LAW
SHE HAD SOME CONFLICTS WITH THE
SCHOOL DISTRICT MOSTLY OVER THE
EDUCATION AND TREATMENT OF ADAM
BUT WHY THAT SCHOOL WAS CHOSEN
AND WHY THOSE KIDS WERE KILLED
STILL A MYSTERY.
>>Bret: THANK YOU, MIKE TOBIN,
FOLLOWING THE INVESTIGATION OF
THE TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN.
AS WE LOOK AGAIN LIVE IN
NEWTOWN, GETTING READY FOR THE
RARE SERVICE AND PRESIDENT OBAMA
MEETING WITH THE VICTIMS'
FAMILIES IN CLASSROOMS IN THE
VERY HIGH SCHOOL.
WE WILL HEAD BACK THIS FOR MORE.
THE PRESIDENT SET TO DELIVER
REMARKS ON BEHALF OF THE
GRIEVING NATION MINUTES FROM
NOW.
initiated.
Neural speeds
increasing to 4G LTE.
Brain upgrading to a quad-core
processor.
Predictive intelligence
with Google Now complete.
Introducing DROID DNA by HTC.
It's not an upgrade
to your phone.
It's an upgrade to yourself.
Yofor giving the perfect gift?le
just have a knack
They put real thought into it.
And find just...
the right...thing.
How do they do that?
More saving. More doing.
That's the power of The
Home Depot.
Pick up a RIDGID JobMax
multi-tool starter kit and
get a free head attachment.
>>Bret: YOU ARE LOOKING LIVE
OUTSIDE THE NEWTOWN HIGH SCHOOL
AUDITORIUM WHERE PRESIDENT OBAMA
WILL SPEAK IN JUST A BIT ONCE A
PRAYER SERVICE STARTS THERE, A
VIGIL.
PEOPLE ARE FILING IN.
WE ARE GETTING WORD THE
VOLUNTEER EFFORT FROM THE
AMERICAN RED CROSS IS
SPECTACULAR.
NOT ONLY TO HELP THE VICTIMS AND
THE FAMILIES AND ALSO THE
FAMILIES IN THE SCHOOL, BUT,
REALLY, EVERYONE THERE.
I CAN TELL YOU THE RED CROSS IS
PROVIDING CRISIS AND GRIEF
COUNSELING FOR EVERYONE AND ALSO
HANDLING, OR HANDING OUT
BLANKETS AND TEDDY BEARS TO KIDS
THROUGH THE TOWN WITH MORE THAN
100 VOLUNTEERS POURING IN FROM
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY TO NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, SO, JUST A SENSE OF
THE FEELING ON THE GROUND FROM
THE AMERICAN RED CROSS AND I CAN
TELL YOU THAT DIFFERENT CHURCH
SERVICES AND SYNAGOGUES WERE
PACKED THROUGHOUT THE REGION.
EARLY TOMORROW -- TODAY, POPE
BENEDICT XVI OFFER CONDOLE ENDS
SAYING HE IS DEEPLY SADDENED AND
IS PRAYING FOR THE FAMILIES OF
THE VICTIMS AND ENCOURAGED
PEOPLE TO WORK FOR PEACE DURING
THE CHRISTMAS SEASON.
>> WE ARE IN PRAYER FOR THE
FAMILIES AND HOPE TO TOWN THEIR
HEARTS AND EASE THEIR PAIN.
>> HOUSES OF WORSHIP TALKED
ABOUT HOW THIS HAPPENED TO THE
MOST INNOCENT OF YOUNG CHILDREN.
JOINING ME IS A FOX NEWS
CONTRIBUTOR AUTHOR OF A BOOK
"GOD WANTS YOU HAPPY," AND A
RABBI WHO HELPED COUNSEL VICTIMS
FOLLOWING THE 9/11 ATTACKS.
RABBI, TELL ME WHERE YOU ARE
FROM.
NOW, RABBI, YOUR THOUGHTS, TELL
US ABOUT TRYING TO COME TO GRIPS
WITH THIS AND WHAT YOU TELL
PEOPLE WHO COME TO YOU AND SAY
SOMETHING LIKE, HOW CAN GOD LET
THIS HAPPEN?
>>Guest: JEWISH RERELIGION IS
FAMILY WITH TERROR AND HORRIFIC
EVENTS BUT IT IS NOT THAT GOD
CAUSES THINGS TO HAPPEN.
GOD DOES NOT CAUSE EVIL THE
PEOPLE DO.
OUR RESPONSIBILITY IS TO REALIZE
IF IT IS PEOPLE WHO ACT, WHO DO
EVIL THINGS, THERE ARE ALSO
PEOPLE WHO DO VERY WONDERFUL
BLESSED THINGS AND WE TAKE THESE
FROM OUR RELIGION THE BENEFITS,
THE BEAUTY, COMING TOGETHER IF
A COMMUNITY, TO OFFER COMFORT TO
THE MOUNTERS -- MOURNERS THAT WE
CAN OFFER BUT RELIGION DOES NOT
BLAME GOD, IT IS INDIVIDUAL
WOULD DO EVIL BUT THE
INDIVIDUALS PICK UP THE PIECES
AND RE-CREATE BLESSINGS IN
PEOPLE'S LIVES.
>>Bret: I AM CATHOLIC AND THIS
IS REJOICE SUNDAY AND POPE
BENEDICT SPEAKS OF HAVING THE
COURAGE TO REJOICE.
IT IS TOUGH TO REJOICE IN THE
WAKE OF THIS PAST WEEK.
>>Guest: IT IS.
IF I WERE THERE RIGHT NOW I
WOULD NOT BE ENCOURAGING PEOPLE
TO REJOICE I WOULD GIVE THEM A
HUG.
THOSE THINGS THAT REMAIN IN
FAMILIES THAT HAVE SUFFERED SO
TRAGICALLY NOT ONLY IN ACTS LIKE
THIS, SO HORRIFIC, BUT THE LOSS
OF A CHILD, NO MATTER HOW IT
HAPPENED, WHAT THEY REMEMBER IS
PEOPLE WHO WERE THERE FOR HIM
AND WHO HUGGED THEM.
SECOND, IF THEY WERE PLEASED
WITH THE GIFT OF FAITH THEY ALSO
REMEMBER THAT MAYBE THERE IS
HEAVEN.
MAYBE THERE IS A SOLUTION.
I WAS WITH MY CHURCH TODAY AND
THEY WERE STREAMING OUT OF
CHURCH AND ONE OF THEM TOOK ME
ASIDE AND SAID, FATHER, ALL I
COULD THINK ABOUT WAS IF MY SIX
OR 7-YEAR-OLD WOULD HAVE BEEN
THERE AND SUFFERED THOSE LAST
FEW MINUTES, I NEVER THOUGHT OF
THAT, THE LAST COUPLE OF
MINUTES, MAYBE THAT SOUNDS
SHOCKING BUT THAT IS THE REALITY
OF THIS.
I BELIEVE DEEPLY AND I BELIEVE
ABSOLUTELY WITH WHAT THE GOOD
RABBI HAS JUST SAID THAT GOD
DOES NOT CAUSE EVIL.
NOT ONLY THAT, GOD WAS THERE
PRESENT AS THIS MAN ABUSED HIS
GOD GIVEN GIFT OF FREEDOM TO DO
EVIL.
JUST AS GOD WAS THERE WITH HIS
OWN SON WHO DIED ON THE CROSS,
BY MURDER, AT THE HANDS OF
ROMANS AND CRIED FOR HIM I
BELIEVE GOD WAS THIS FOR THE
CHILDREN AS THEY SUFFERED THEIR
LAST.
THAT IS NOT A PERFECT SOLUTION
OR ANSWER TO THIS BUT IT IS A
GOING AND THE FACT THAT THERE IS
ETERNAL LIFE IN MY OPINION FROM
THE CHRISTIAN PERSPECTIVE, IT IS
A GREAT START AND AS TIME GOES
ON AND OTHER QUESTIONS COME IN
AS I AM SURE THE RABBI AND I
HAVE BOTH RECEIVES, IN TIME,
THERE ARE DEEPER QUESTIONS OF
HOW GOD WOULD PERMIT IT TO COME
INTO PLAY.
>>Bret: THANK YOU, FATHER
MORRIS, AND RABBI, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH, YOUR WORDS ARE VERY
THOUGHTFUL.
MORE AS WE GET READY TO HEAR
FROM REBOUND IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
[ Male Announcer ] Alka-Seltzer
Plus PRESENTS THE Cold Truth.
I HAVE A COLD,
AND I TOOK NYQUIL,
BUT I'M STILL "STUBBED" UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT DOESN'T HAVE A DECONGESTANT.
NO WAY.
[ Male Announcer ] SORRY.
Alka-Seltzer Plus FIGHTS
YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A FAST ACTING
DECONGESTANT
TO RELIEVE YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
[ sighs ] THANKS!
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus.
♪ OH
WHAT A RELIEF IT IS! ♪
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
AND SAVE $1
VISIT Alka-Seltzer ON FACEBOOK.
>> STILL WAITING FOR THE START
OF THE VIGIL IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WHERE THOUSANDS ARE
MOURNING THE LIVES OF THOSE LOST
AT THE SHOOTING.
THIS IS THE AUDITORIUM AS PEOPLE
ARE GETTING SEATED.
THE PRESIDENT IS MEETING WITH
THE VICTIMS' FAMILY MEMBERS.
SOME OF THE FAMILIES, AS WELL AS
PEOPLE STILL STREAMING IN FROM
THE OUTSIDE HOLDING BALLOONS, IN
LINE, AND ALSO MEETING WITH
FIRST RESPONDERS, THE PRESIDENT
IS.
THAT JOB, THE FIRST SPENDERS TO
THE GRIZZLY SCENE, TRULY AMAZING
WHAT THEY HAD TO GO THROUGH TO
SECURE THE SCENE AND LOOK AT
WHAT THEY LOOKED AT IN THE TWO
CLASSROOMS, THE NATION'S GRIEF
SPEWING ON TO THE AIRWAVES AND
WE GOT NOW REACTION FROM
LAWMAKERS ON BOTH SIDES OF THE
AISLE.
STEVE IS LIVE HERE IN WASHINGTON
WITH MORE.
STEVE?
>> HEAR IN WASHINGTON, DC, SHOCK
AND SADNESS, BUT, ALSO, A NEW
DETERMINATION TO LOOK AT ALL THE
POSSIBLE WAYS ANOTHER TRAGEDY
COULD BE PREVENTED.
OUTGOING SENATOR JOE LIEBERMAN,
AN INDEPENDENT FROM CONNECTICUT,
HAD THIS OBSERVATION ABOUT GUN
CONTROL.
>> THE SAME FOR DEMOCRATS,
REPUBLICANS, AND INDEPENDENTS,
TO ACKNOWLEDGE TWO THINGS: ONE,
THE STRONGEST CONCEIVABLE GUN
CONTROL LAWS WILL NOT STOP ALL
ACTS OF VIOLENCE.
BUT, ALSO, KNOWLEDGE THAT THE
STRONGER OUR GUN CONTROL LAWS
ARE, THE FEWER ACTS VIOLENCE
INCLUDING MASS VIOLENCE, WILL
HAPPEN IN OUR SOCIETY.
>> HE GOES FURTHER AND PROPOSE
AS NATIONAL COMMISSION, AND
SENATOR DURBIN EXPRESSED
SUPPORT.
TOM RIDGE SERVED ON A STATE
COMMISSION TO INVESTIGATE THE
VIRGINIA TECH SHOOTINGS FIVE
YEARS AGO AND SAID THIS IS A
COMPLEX PROBLEM THAT NEEDS
CAREFUL ATTENTION.
>> THERE ARE MULTIPLE PLAYERS
HERE TOMORROW HAVE A SERIOUS
CONVERSATION ABOUT REDUCING THE
RISK OF THIS HAPPENING, WE HAVE
TO START DEALING WITH ALL THE
LAYERS.
IT IS ABOUT LIFECY, AND MENTAL
HEALTH CANCELING AND GETTING THE
PEOPLE THE HELP THEY NEED AT THE
OUTSET.
>> ALSO TURNING THE SPOT LIGHT
ON MENTAL HEALTH SCREENING AND
ON CULTURAL ISSUES.
SENATOR LIEBERMAN AND REPUBLICAN
CONGRESSMAN FROM UTAH BOTH
SUGGESTING TODAY THAT THE MASS
MEDIA INCLUDING VIOLENT VIDEO
GAMES NEGATIVELY INFLUENCE
IMPRESSIONABLE TEEN BOYS AND
SOME CALL TODAY FOR TOUGHER
REGULATIONS INCLUDING A BAN ON
ASSAULT WEAPONS.
>>Bret: THANK YOU, STEVE.
NOW, BRINGING BACK OUR PANEL,
SENIOR WRITER FOR THE WEEKLY
STANDARD, STEVEN STEPHEN HAYESSD
CHARLES KRAUTHAMMER.
WE TALK ABOUT THIS EARLIER,
STEVE, AND SOME CALLED FOR GUN
CONTROL, TODAY, AND YOU HEARD
SOME TALKING ABOUT MENTAL
ILLNESS AND HOW BIG A PROBLEM
THAT IS AND BEING LOOKED AT.
POLICY-WISE, BEYOND THIS SPEECH
TONIGHT, BECAUSE ED IS SAYING
THAT, REALLY, THAT IS NOT THE
FOCUS.
WHERE DOES THIS GO?
>> WE WILL HAVE A BIG DEBATE
ABOUT GUN CONTROL.
WE HAVE SEEN THAT TAKING PLACE.
PEOPLE LIKE BLOOMBERG HAS HAD
THIS FOR A CAUSE A GOOD MANY
YEARS.
I DO HOPE WE ALSO HAVE A
SUSTAINED DEBATE ABOUT CIVIL
COMMITMENT AND HOW WE DEAL WITH
MENTAL ILLNESS.
IT IS VERY CLEAR WHEN YOU LOOK
BACK AT THE SERIES OF SHOOTINGS
WE HAVE HAD, OUR SOCIETY HAS BIG
QUESTIONS TO ANSWER ON HOW TO
DEAL WITH THE MENTALLY ILL AND
DANGEROUSLY MENTALLY ILL, THE
PEOPLE, WHERE THERE IS A SOCIETY
THAT DOES NOT WANT TO CATEGORIZE
PEOPLE OR COMMIT PEOPLE BUT
CLEARLY WHAT WE ARE DOING IS NOT
WORKING.
THAT HAS TO BE PART OF THIS
BROADER DISCUSSION.
>>Bret: THERE WAS AN AMAZING
PIECE ON TWITTER, "I AM ADAM
LANZA'S MOTHER" WRITTEN BY A
MOTHER WHO DESCRIBED IN VERY
GREAT DETAIL HAVING A SON WHO
THREATENED HER AND SHE HAD TO
DEAL WITH IT.
IF YOU HAVE NOT READ IT IT IS
WORTH READING.
IT IS ABOUT MENTAL ILLNESS AND
HOW SHE ESSENTIALLY SAYS THAT NO
ONE WOULD TAKE HER SERIOUSLY
UNLESS HER CHILD HAD A CRIMINAL
RECORD.
>> THAT IS TRAGEDY.
MANY YEARS AGO I WOULD COMMIT
PEOPLE AGAINST THEIR WILL FOR
THE MASSACHUSETTS GENERAL
HOSPITAL TO STATE HOSPITALS IF
THEY WERE A DANGER TO THEMSELVES
OR OTHERS.
IT IS HADDER TO DO AND NOT
SOMETHING ANY PSYCHIATRIST DOES
LIGHTLY BUT THE DILEMMA FOR A
PARENT, YOU ARE IN THE TERRIBLE
RELATIONSHIPS, THING OF
LOUGHNER, FROM SUE -- SUE --
FROM TUCSON, EVERYONE KNEW HE
WAS NOT WELL AND KNEW HE WAS
DANGEROUS.
ONE STUDENT FLED THE CLASS IF HE
WAS THERE, SHE SAT IN THE BACK
SO SHE COULD ESCAPE.
YOU HAVE A PARENT WHO KNOWS THIS
IS GOING ON AND IS TOLD BY THE
AUTHORITIES BECAUSE OF THE RISE
OF CIVIL LIBERTIES AND THE
EXPERIENCE WE HAD IN THE 50'S OF
THE ABUSE OF INCARCERATION OF
MENTALLY ILL, IT BECOMES
IMPOSSIBLE AND THEY SAY TO A
PARENT UNLESS HE DOES SOMETHING
OUR HANDS ARE TIED.
THAT IS A TERRIBLE TRAGEDY.
THE PARENTS ARE CAUGHT IN AN
IMPOSSIBLE SITUATION.
IT IS NOT UNTIL THE LOUGHNERS
COMMIT THE ATROCITY THAT THE
STATE STEPS IN AND IN HIS CASE
IT WAS OBVIOUS FROM THE MOMENT
THIS HAPPENED.
WE DO NOT KNOW ABOUT ADAM LANZA
BUT IT IS A PICTURE OF A
WITHDRAWN AND POSSIBLY AUTISTIC
CHILD, WITH VIDEO GAMES AND HELP
CLOSED IN HIS WORD, A PARENT
LIVING ALONE WITH HIP, OBVIOUSLY
UNABLE TO COPE WITH THE TERRIBLE
TRAGEDY HAPPENS.
WHAT IS THE FIRST THING HE DOES
ON THE HORRIBLE DAY?
HE KILLS HIS MOTHER.
THIS IS A SITUATION WHERE I
EMPATHIZE WITH EVERY PARENT OR
RELATIVE.
WHERE DO YOU TURN UNDER THE
COUNTRY LAWS?
>>Bret: THE ASSOCIATE PRESS IS
QUOTING THE BUREAU OF ALCOHOL
AND TOBACCO AND FIREARMS SAYING
ADAM LANZA HAD BEEN VISITING A
LOCAL SHOOTING RANGE BUT THEY DO
NOT KNOW IF HE PRACTICED THERE
BUT THEY KNOW HIS MOTHER VISITED
THE SHOOTING RANGES SEVERAL
TIMES, WHETHER SHE TOOK HIM
THERE TO PRACTICE WITH HER, THEY
ARE THOUGHT SAYING, BUT HE DID
GO THERE.
SO THE QUOTE, AGAIN, WE JUST
DON'T KNOW THAT MUCH.
WE KNOW THAT HE TOOK HER GUNS TO
DO THIS CRIME.
>>Guest: SHE WAS A GUN
COLLECTOR AND WENT TO THE
SHOOTING RANGE WITH
SEMI-AUTOMATIC WEAPONS.
IT IS REALLY IMPORTANT AS WE
MOVE FORWARD IN THIS, WHAT
CHARLES BRINGS UP IS ABSOLUTELY
RIGHT, IT IS VERY HARD FOR A
PARENT TO COMMIT A CHILD AND IT
IS CLEAR FROM THE PAST MASS
KILLINGS THERE WERE WARNING
SIGNS AND WE MAY FIND THAT OUT
NOW.
THE OTHER COMPONENT IS THE RISE
AND PROLIFERATION OF
SEMI-AUTOMATIC WEAPONS WHICH ARE
TIED TO EVERYONE OF THE MASS
KILLING.
WE HAVE TO KEEP IN MIND THE BODY
OF A SIX-YEAR OLD, THESE
CHILDREN FROM THREE TO 11
WOUNDS.
THEY DIDN'T HAVE A CHANCE.
THAT HAS TO BE PART OF THIS
CONVERSATION.
AFTER 9/11, WE HAD A
CONVERSATION ABOUT RIGHTS.
WE DE THE
TIME.
THE GOVERNMENT HAS US UNDER
SURVEILLANCE AND WE AGREED WE
WANTED TO DO THAT FOR THE SAFETY
OF OUR NATION AND THAT IS A
CONVERSATION WE NEED TO DO ABOUT
THE SAFETY OF OUR CHILDREN.
>>Bret: AND THE OTHER SIDE
WILL SAY ONCE THIS HAPPENS IT
OPENS THE DOORS TO ALL KINDS OF
THINGS AND GUNS ARE UNDER
ATTACK.
THIS IS NOT THE TIME TO, REALLY,
HAVE THIS BATTLE BUT --.
>> WE NEED A CONVERSATION ABOUT
THAT.
AND THE BULLETS WERE SPECIAL
KIND OF BULLET THAT LODGES AND
IT IS IMPOSSIBLE TO SURVIVE.
WE NEED TO LOOK AT WHY CIVILIANS
NEED THIS.
I LIKE THE IDEA OF A NATIONAL
COMMISSION BECAUSE IT IS NOT
JUST LOOKING AT GUN ASPECT BUT
IT IS LOOKING AT -- IT IS
COMPLICATED.
IT IS THE MENTAL ILLNESS OR THE
VIDEO GAMES OR THE CULTURE, OR
THAT THE FATHER IS NOT AROUND, A
LOT OF DIFFERENT THINGS GOING ON
HERE.
IT NEEDS TO BE LOOKED AT.
NO QUESTION.
>>Bret: WHEN I SAY THIS IS NOT
THE TIME, THE CONVERSATION WILL
BE HAPPENS THIS DAYS AHEAD BUT
WE ARE WAITING FOR THE
PRESIDENT'S REMARKS AS
CONSOLER-IN-CHIEF IN NEWTOWN,
ACCOUNTING FOR ALL THE PEOPLE
FILING IN IN THE AUDITORIUM.
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
CAMPBELL'S HAS 24 NEW SOUPS
THAT WILL MAKE IT DROP OVER,
AND OVER AGAIN.
♪
FROM JAMMIN' JERK CHICKEN,
TO CREAMY GOUDA BISQUE.
SEE WHAT'S NEW FROM CAMPBELL'S.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
Neural speeds
increasing to 4G LTE.
Brain upgrading to a quad-core
processor.
Predictive intelligence
with Google Now complete.
Introducing DROID DNA by HTC.
It's not an upgrade
to your phone.
It's an upgrade to yourself.
BET BRET: LOOKING OUTSIDE THE
HIGH SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN AT THE
HIGH SCHOOL.
PEOPLE ARE STILL FILING IN, AND
IT IS RAINING OR MISTING AND
THAT FITS THE SOMBER MOOD AS THE
CITY IS DEALING WITH THE LOSS
AND THE UNTHINKABLE TRAGEDY, 20
CHILDREN KILLED IN THAT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL ON FRIDAY
MORNING.
THIS COMES AS STUDENTS ACROSS
THE COUNTRY PREPARE TO GO BACK
TO SCHOOL OBVIOUSLY ON MONDAY
WITH THE INVESTIGATION ONGOING
OFFICIALS ARE FACING ANOTHER
CHALLENGE THIS IN NEWTOWN.
THAT IS, TRYING TO GET THINGS
BACK TO NORMAL AS MUCH AS
POSSIBLE FOR THE YOUNG STUDENTS
WHO LIVED THROUGH THE MASSACRE
EARLY TODAY WITH THE CONNECTICUT
GOVERNOR ASKING IF THE CHILDREN
ARE READY TO RETURN TO CLASSES.
>> I THINK THAT IS A DECISION
FOR PARENTS TO MAKE.
IT IS OUR OBLIGATION TO OPEN
SCHOOL.
THAT IS WHAT WE WILL DO.
OBVIOUSLY, A LOT PEOPLE WOULD
LIKE TO GET BACK TO WHATEVER
"NORMAL" WILL LOOK LIKE AS
QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE.
>>Bret: RIGHT NOW IT IS NOT
CHEER WHEN SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
WILL RE-OPEN.
WE TOLD THE STUDENTS FROM THERE
SHOULD BE ASSIGNED TO ATTEND
OTHER SCHOOLS BY WEDNESDAY.
AS I SAID, STUDENTS FROM ACROSS
THE COUNTRY ARE PREPARING TO
RETURN TO SCHOOL, TO CLASS
TOMORROW, AND SCHOOL OFFICIALS
NATIONWIDE ARE LOOKING AT
SECURITY IN THE WAKE OF THE
MASTER WHAT MORE CAN BE DONE TO
PROTECT STUDENTS AT A TIME WHEN
BUDGETS ARE TIGHT?
DOMINIC IS LIVE IN LOS ANGELES
WITH THAT PART OF THE STORY.
>> WE HAVE SEEN A NUMBER OF CUTS
AT THE FEDERAL AND LOCAL LEVELS
AND IT DOES NOT NEED TO COST
THAT MUCH ACCORDING TO THE
EXPERTS.
THE MEASURES TO KEEP SCHOOLS
SAFE ARE WELL ESTABLISHED THAT
COULD PREVENTED FURTHER TERRIBLE
TRAGEDIES.
WHAT IS NEEDED, ACCORDING TO THE
ADVISOR IS COMMUNITY VIGILANCE
AND MORE CLOSELY MONITORED
ACCESS COMBINED WITH BETTER
COORDINATION WITH THE
AUTHORITIES AND THEY SAY THAT IS
NOT VERY HARD TO DO.
>> WE DO NOT WANT THIS TO FADE
AWAY IN A MONTH OR TWO.
THE BIG PROBLEM IS WE FEEL WE
ARE IN DENIAL AND THIS COULD
NEVER HAPPEN TO OUR COMMUNITY OR
OUR SCHOOLS.
>> MANY PARENTS CONTACTED THE
SCHOOLS TO LEARN OF THEIR PLAN.
>>Bret: THANK YOU, DOMINIC.
THEY WERE NO OLDER THAN SIX OR
SEVEN, 20 CHILDREN, GUNNED DOWN
BY A KILLER AND HE ALSO MURDERED
SEVEN ADULTS.
TONIGHT OUR COUNTRY'S THOUGHTS
AND PRAYERS OFFERED UP TO THE
VICTIMS AND THEIR FAMILIES AS
PRESIDENT OBAMA JOINTS THE
COMMUNITY IN MOURNING FOR A
MEMORIAL SERVICE AND PRAYER
VIGIL.
LIVE COVERAGE OF THE TRAGEDY IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUTS CONTINUES
AS THEY LINE INTO THE
AUDITORIUM.
THAT IS NEXT.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'VE REACHED THE AGE
WHERE YOU DON'T BACK DOWN
FROM A CHALLENGE.
THIS IS THE AGE OF KNOWING
HOW TO MAKE THINGS HAPPEN.
SOWHY LET
ERECTILE DYSFUNCTION
GET IN YOUR WAY?
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT VIAGRA.
20 MILLION MEN ALREADY HAVE.
ASK YOUR DOCTOR IF YOUR HEART
IS HEALTHY ENOUGH FOR SEX.
DO NOT TAKE VIAGRA IF YOU TAKE
NITRATES FOR CHEST PAIN;
IT MAY CAUSE AN UNSAFE DROP
IN BLOOD PRESSURE.
SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE
HEADACHE, FLUSHING,
UPSET STOMACH,
AND ABNORMAL VISION.
TO AVOID LONG-TERM INJURY,
SEEK IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
FOR AN ERECTION
LASTING MORE THAN FOUR HOURS.
STOP TAKING VIAGRA
AND CALL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU EXPERIENCE
A SUDDEN DECREASE OR LOSS
IN VISION OR HEARING.
THIS IS THE AGE
OF TAKING ACTION.
VIAGRA.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR.
WELCOME BACK TO SPECIAL
COVERAGE, THE PAIN AND ANGUISH
CAN BE SEEN IN A NUMBER OF
MEMORIALS DOTTING THAT USUAL
QUIET PLACE, THIS ONE A
COLLECTION OF 27 HANDMADE
ANGELS LINING A HILL SIDE.
AND MOTORISTS OVER TAKEN BY
THE SIDE TO SLOW DOWN AND TAKE
A LONGER LOOK TODAY AND OTHERS
GETTING OUT OF THEIR CARS TO
TAKE PICTURES AND EACH OF THE
ANGELS THE WORK OF 20-YEAR-OLD
ERIC MULLER, A PRIVATE SCHOOL
ART TEACHER AND HE SAYS HE
DIDN'T KNOW ANY OF THE VICTIMS
THAT DIED, BUT FELT COMPELLED
TO DO SOMETHING AND THE SAME
GRIEF REALLY FELT IN EVERY
CORNER.
UNITED STATES AND THOUSANDS OF
MILES AWAY IN SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA, MOURNERS THERE
HOLDING A PRAYER SERVICE TO
REMEMBER THE INNOCENT LIVES
LOST AND THEIR FAMILIES NOW
DEALING WITH THE TRAGEDY.
>> THE OTHER ADMINISTRATORS
WHO WENT TOWARDS HIM AND TRIED
TO PROTECT THE KIDS, THAT JUST
GETS ME, CATCHES ME.
>> I WOKE UP AT LIKE 1:30 THIS
MORNING WITH A PIECE OF
SCRIPTURE GOING THROUGH MY
HEAD FROM JEREMIAH, AND RACHEL
WEEPING AND WINNER WITH HER NO
MORE AND I WOKE UP CRYING AND
COULDN'T STOP CRYING AND
THOUGHT YOU KNOW, OTHER PEOPLE
NEED TO CRY, TOO.
>> OUR PANEL IS BACK WITH US
NOW.
YOU KNOW, WE'VE TALKED A
LITTLE ABOUT THE POLICIES
SURROUNDING ALL OF THIS, BUT
YOU KNOW, DEALING WITH IT,
CHARLES, HAS BEEN FRANKLY
TOUGH FOR A LOT OF PEOPLE.
>> WELL, IT'S VERY HARD.
WE HAVE THE MASS MEDIA AND
EVER SINCE THE KENNEDY
ASSASSINATION WHEN THESE
THINGS HAPPEN WE BECOME A
COMMUNITY.
THAT WAS THE REALLY THE FIRST
TIME WE NATIONALLY MOURNED AND
IT'S VERY DIFFICULT TO DO.
I THINK WHEN WE TALK ABOUT IT
HAPPENING AT THE COMMUNITY
LEVEL, AT THE FAMILY LEVEL,
THERE ARE THESE MENTAL HEALTH
EXPERTS WHO GO IN AND THEY
COUNSEL AND I THINK THEY DO AN
EXTRAORDINARY JOB.
BUT IN THE END WE REALLY COME
UP AGAINST THAT QUESTION THAT
YOU ASKED THE RABBI EARLIER IN
THE SHOW FOR THESE, I MEAN,
THE MOST PROFOUND EXPLANATIONS
ARE OFTEN THE MOST, OR
THEOLOGICAL AND WE REALLY
DON'T HAVE VERY GOOD
THEOLOGICAL EXPLANATIONS, IT'S
CALLED THE PROBLEM OF THE
PRESENCE OF EVIL AND THE
PRESENCE OF GOD, ALL LOVING
GOD.
AS HUMANS, WE REALLY DON'T.
WHEN YOU ASK HOW DO YOU
COUNSEL PEOPLE, THERE'S REALLY
NOTHING ONE CAN OFFER IN THE
WAY OF EXPLANATION, OTHER THAN
LOVE AND PROTECTION, REALLY.
>> AND IT'S ALSO TOUGH TO --
IT'S TOUGH TO DO YOUR JOB WHEN
YOU'RE THERE AS A FIRST
RESPONDER, TO RESPOND TO
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
I DON'T WANT TO SAY IT'S TOUGH
TO BE A MEDIA PERSON, BUT IT
IS TO COVER SOMETHING LIKE
THIS WHEN YOU'RE ON THE GROUND
AND TRY TO GET THE STORY, TO
BRING IT OUT TO PEOPLE.
A LOT OF PEOPLE, YOU KNOW,
DON'T LIKE REPORTERS BECAUSE
THEY'RE ASKING PEOPLE
QUESTIONS AND SAYING, YOU
KNOW, WILL YOU TALK TO US.
ONE OF THE FATHERS DID TALK TO
THE CAMERAS TODAY AND CHOSE TO
DO SO AND HERE IS WHAT HE HAD
TO SAY.
>> SHE NEVER MISSED AN
OPPORTUNITY TO DRAW A PICTURE
OR MAKE A CARD FOR THOSE
AROUND HER.
I CAN'T COUNT THE NUMBER OF
TIMES EMILIE NOTICED SOMEONE
FEELING SAD AND RUSHED TO FIND
PAPER AND DRAW A PICTURE OR
ENCOURAGING NOTES.
AND HER LAUGHTER WAS
INFECTIOUS AND ALL THOSE WHO
HAD THE PLEASURE TO MEET HER,
THIS WORLD IS A BETTER PLACE
BECAUSE SHE'S BEEN IN IT.
>> AND THERE'S AN INSTANCE TO
SAY GET OUT OF HERE, DROP THIS
STORY AND LEAVE THEM ALONE.
AND THEN THERE'S THIS OTHER
INSTINCT THAT THERE'S THIS
HEALING THAT NEEDS TO HAPPEN
AND THIS PRAYER SERVICE
TONIGHT IS PART OF IT.
>> WE'RE GOING TO HEAR MORE
STORIES LIKE THAT, AND MORE
PARENTS TALK AND IT'S SO HARD
TO LISTEN TO THAT FATHER
WITHOUT CHOKING UP.
AND WHAT BOTHERS ME, I
REMEMBER COLUMBINE AND PAIN
WHEN THE CHILDREN WERE KILLED
IN COLORADO AND I VIVIDLY
REMEMBER VIRGINIA TECH, WAS
EVEN BIGGER FATALITY-WISE AND
MORE KIDS DIED AND WE HAVE
THIS LIKE TROUBLING SHORT-TERM
MEMORY IN THIS COUNTRY WHERE
WE FIXATE ON THIS FOR A
RELATIVELY SHORT PERIOD OF
TIME AND THEN WE MOVE ON.
SO I HOPE THOSE PARENTS COMING
FORWARD NOW AND TALKING ABOUT
THESE SMALL CHILDREN WILL
ACTUALLY PROVIDE SOME LEVEL OF
TIPPING POINT, SOME LEVEL OF
MOVEMENT, SOME LEVEL OF FOCUS
ON OUR COUNTRY TO AT LEAST
START THE CONVERSATION AND
HAVE A COMMISSION TO LOOK AT
THIS AND TRY TO TAKE ACTION
AND NOT JUST THROW UP OUR
HANDS AND WAIT FOR THE NEXT
ONE TO HAPPEN.
>> AND I ALSO THINK THAT YOU
LOOK AT THE CHILDREN AP IT'S
SO INCREDIBLY TRAGIC, THE
PICTURE THAT WE BUMPED IN AND
THE PICTURE WAS ICONIC, THE
WOMAN SOBBING IN THE PARKING
LOT THAT'S ACTUALLY THE SISTER
OF VICTORIA SOTTO, WHO WAS THE
TEACHER WHO SAVED SOME OF HER
CHIL