WEDDING.
DRIVING 100 MILES PER HOUR
DOING THE HIGHWAY.
THE COP GOES AFTER HIM, AND HE
PULLS IN A CHURCH, DOES
DOUGHNUTS, ALMOST TIPS THE CAR
OVER, GETS DOWN, ARRESTED.
NO WEDDING.
BACK IN JAIL.
NOT A SMART MOVE.
NOT AT ALL.
>> Greg: OR MAYBE A GREAT
MOVE BECAUSE HE DIDN'T GET
MARRIED.
>> Bob: THAT IS A THOUGHT.
IT HADN'T THOUGHT OF THAT.
I SHOULD HAVE.
>> Greg: THAT IS IT FOR US
ON FIV "THE FIVE."
THANKS FOR WATCHING.
SEE YOU TOMORROW.
Captioned By
Closed Captioning Services, Inc
>> Bret: REPUBLICANS PREPARE
TO VOTE ON PLAN "B."
A DUAL TRACK IN NEGOTIATIONS
FALL APART.
SO FAR, IT SEEMS HEADING THAT
WAY.
SO WHAT NOW?
THIS IS "SPECIAL REPORT."
♪
>> Bret: GOOD EVENING.
I'M BRET BAIER.
WITH THE FISCAL CLIFF LOOMING,
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND BARACK
OBAMA; OBAMA AND HOUSE SPEAKER
BOEHNER I SHOULD SAY CONTINUE
TO FIGHT TOOTH AND NAIL OVER
HOW BEST TO AVERT THE
AUTOMATTIC TAX HIKES AND
SPENDING CUTS THAT WOULD GO IN
EFFECT, EXACTLY TWO WEEKS FROM
TONIGHT.
WE HAVE TEAM FOX COVERAGE
TONIGHT WITH CHIEF POLITICAL
CORRESPONDENT CARL CAMERON ON
CAPITOL HILL, WHERE THE HOUSE
IS SET TO VOTE ON WHAT SPEAKER
BOEHNER CALLS A PLAN "B."
BUT WE START AND YOU HAVE MAY
HAVE SEEN HIM WITH THE CHIEF
WASHINGTON CORRESPONDENT ED
HENRY WHERE OBAMA INSISTS HE
MOVED MORE THAN HALFWAY TO
MEET BOEHNER.
>> Megyn: THE DEMOCRATS HAVE
GIVEN A LOT TO BOEHNER AND
THEY ARE NOT READY TO GIVE
MORE.
TOP ADVISOR TELLING ME THE
WHITE HOUSE BELIEVES THE
NEGOTIATION TOOK A STEP BACK
TODAY.
SPEAKER BOEHNER SAID IT'S TIME
FOR A BACKUP PLAN.
>> OUR PLAN "B" IS PROTECT
TAXPAYERS MAKING $1 MILLION OR
LESS AND HAVE CURRENT RATES
EXTENDED.
>> THERE THERE IS LITTLE
CHANCE OF PASSIBLE IN THE
SENATE.
THE DEMOCRATS SAY IF GOALPOSTS
IS GETTING MOVED.
>> TAKE THE FOOTBALL AND
CHARLIE BROWN EPISODE.
THEY JERK IT AWAY.
>> 15 MONTHS AGO THE PRESIDENT
SUGGESTED THRESHOLD ON TAX
HIKES MIGHT BE A $1 MILLION.
>> MIDDLE CLASS FAMILIES
SHOULDN'T PAY HIGHER TAXES
THAN MILLIONAIRE AND
BILLIONAIRES.
TODAY THEY SAID IT DID NOT
PRECLUDE RAISING RATES WITH
BROADER REFORM.
>> THE IDEA TO TAX PEOPLE
MAKING MORE THAN $1 MILLION IS
SO BAD AND UNBALANCED WHY DID
THE PRESIDENT PROPOSE IT IN
2007?
>> MILLIONAIRE TAX IN ROSE
GARDEN?
>> FIRST,
>> THAT IS A DIFFERENT
PROPOISE SAL.
HE SUPPORTED EXPLORATION OF
BUSH TAX CUT FOR THOSE MAKING
MORE THAN $250,000.
>> PRIVATE TALKS, PRESIDENT
MOVED THE THRESHOLD TO
$400,000 OR MORE.
IS REPUBLICANS NOTED 5653
SENATE DEMOCRATS VOTED FOR A
PLAN BY SCHUMER THAT SOUNDS
SIMILAR TO BOEHNER.
>> SENATOR SCHUMER SAID FIRST
I DON'T KNOW A SINGLE ONE OF
MY COLLEAGUES WHO WOULD ABOUT
PREFER TAX BREAKS IFER PEOPLE
UP TO $1 MILLION.
>> BOEHNER HAS BIGGER PROBLE
PROBLEMS.
HE HAS A BILL FOR TAX CUTS FOR
ANYONE MAKING $250,000 OR
LESS.
THAT COULD HELP AVOID THE
CLIFF, SINCE THE SENATE
ALREADY APPROVED IT.
CONSERVATIVES ARE LIKELY TO
BLOCK IT.
>> OUR JOB IS KEEP IT AS LOW
AS POSSIBLE NOW.
GET 99% OF AMERICANS NOT HAVE
A TAX INCREASE.
THAT IS GOAL.
>> Reporter: MEANING WITH
THE CLOCK TICKING THE
DEMOCRATS THINK THEY HAVE
BOEHNER BOXED IN.
>> WE DON'T KNOW DETAILS OF
PLAN "A" OR "B" OR WHATEVER
PLAN "C" MIGHT BE.
BUT WE REMAIN UNITED BEHIND
OUR PRESIDENT.
>> THIS IS WHAT PLAN "C" MIGHT
LOOK LIKE.
THEY CAN SEE SCENARIO THAT
PRESIDENT MAKES ONE MORE
CONCESSION, THAT THRESHOLD
COULD BE $500,000 FOR THE TAX
INCREASES.
BOEHNER MAY NOT TAKE IT.
IT DOESN'T INCLUDE MAJOR
SPENDING CUTS OR INCREASE IN
THE DEBT CEILING.
SO THIS LEAVES A LOT ON THE
TABLE EITHER WAY.
>> Bret: THANK YOU.
WHAT IS NEXT IN BACK AND
FORTH?
CHECK IN NOW WITH THE CHIEF
POLITICAL CORRESPONDENT CARL
CAMERON FROM CAPITOL HILL.
GOOD EVENING.
ED MENTIONED THAT SPEAKER
BOEHNER PUT INCREASED TAX
REVENUE ON THE TABLE, SOME
CONSERVATIVES WERE FEARING
IT'S REVENUE FROM CLOSING TAX
LOOPHOLE AND DEDUCTION.
NOW IT'S TAX INCREASE.
INCREASING RATES FOR
MILLIONAIRES.
WHAT ARE YOU HEARING THERE?
>> HOUSE REPUBLICANS HAVE A
CLOSED DOOR MEETING WITH THE
LEADERSHIP RIGHT NOW ON THE
HOUSE SIDE.
WE TALKED TO SOME MEMBERS WHO
HAVE GONE IN AND OUT.
A COMBINATION OF CONSTERNATION
AND FRUSTRATION.
AND MYSTIFICATION.
THEY DON'T KNOW WHAT IS GOING
TO HAPPEN.
JUST FINDING OUT THE DETAILS.
THAT IS RIGHT NOW.
TOMORROW THERE WILL BE A
PROTEST OUTSIDE THE CAPITAL OF
OUTSIDE GROUPS THAT THINK THAT
THE REPUBLICANS ARE GIVING IN
TOO MUCH.
IT WILL BE CALLED THE HOLD THE
LINE RALLY.
URGING AGAINST ANYTHING THAT
WOULD COUNTER THE RATE
INCREASE.
AND REVENUE INCREASES ARE ON
THE TABLE.
MR. BOEHNER HAS PROBLEMS WITH
THE CAUCUS.
MOST OF THE MEMBER ARE QUIET.
OUTSIDE GROUPS HAVE BEEN
HARSH.
CLUB FOR GROWTH AND HAIR TAGE
FOUNDATION ARE BEHIND THIS TO
SAY THAT THE SPEAKER IS OUT OF
LINE.
BUT TO THIS POINT HE HAS HAD
THE BENEFIT OF HIS LEADERSHIP
HOLDING WITH HIM.
THE MAJORITY LEADER ERIC
CANTOR, WHIP, McCARTHY AND
RYAN BEHIND HIM.
THAT KEPT THE REPUBLICAN
CONFERENCE TOGETHER.
IT COULD FRAY DEPENDING ON HOW
THE VOTE GOES.
>> Bret: SPEAKER BOEHNER
USED THE DUAL TRAP BEFORE,
WITH THE DEBT CEILING AND HOW
HE ORCHESTRATED THAT
NEGOTIATION BACK THEN.
IF THE HOUSE GOES AHEAD WITH
THE VOTES ON THURSDAY, CARL,
BOEHNER'S PLAN "B" COULD
BECOME A MULTIPLE CHOICE.
>> YOU HEARD WHAT ED WHENLY
WAS TALKING ABOUT THERE.
FIRST THE VOTE ON THE PLAN.
THEY ANTICIPATE AN HOPE IT
WILL BE DEFEATED EASILY WITH
THE REPUBLICAN MAJORITY.
THE PLAN "B" IS THAT
MILLION-DOLLAR THRESHOLD, OPEN
QUESTION.
THERE ARE REPUBLICANS WHO HAVE
ISSUES WITH IT.
AND PART OF THE CONSTERNATION
THEY EXPRESS IS WHEN THE
PRESIDENT OFFERED $400,000,
WHY WOULD MR. BOEHNER TAKE SO
IT FAR OUT OF WHAT HAS BEEN
NARROWING NEGOTIATING PROCESS?
COULD IT BLOW UP ON HIM?
THIS IS THE THING THAT IF
MR. BOEHNER DOESN'T PLAY IT
RIGHT, THERE ARE THREATS TO
HIS SPEAKERSHIP.
BECAUSE OF THE NATURE OF HOW
THE REPUBLICAN CONGRESS IS
BALANCED HE COULD LOUIS EIGHT
VOTES FOR ELECTION OF SPEAKER
HE WOULDN'T BE IT FOR THE NEXT
UPCOMING SESSION.
>> MORE ON THIS WITH THE
PANEL.
WE ARE TALKING TAXES HERE BUT
IT COMES DOWN TO SPENDING AS
WELL.
CAPITOL HILL CONTINUES TO
WRESTLE WITH THE WHITE HOUSE.
OVER WHAT TO CUT, AND WHERE.
AND HOW MUCH, YOU HAVE TO
UNDERSTAND THAT THIS BACK AND
FORTH IS REALLY TINY.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT THE FISCAL
HOLE THE NATION IS FACING.
HAVE YOU WONDERED HOW MUCH OF
THE NATIONAL DEBT YOU AND YOUR
FAMILY OWE?
WE TAKE A LOOK AT STAGGERING
NUMBERS TONIGHT IN PART TWO OF
THE SERIES "THE COST OF
SPENDING."
>> THE NATIONAL DEBT CLOCK,
SPINNING FASTER EVER YEAR.
WE HAVE ALL SEEN IT BEFORE.
>> DID YOU SEE THAT CLOCK UP
THERE?
$16 TRILLION OF DEBT.
>> USED AS PROP AT CAMPAIGN
EVENTS.
>> WHEN THE COME PAIN BEGAN IT
WAS LESS THAN THAT.
>> YOU CAN WALK BY THE MAIN
DEBT CLOCK IN NEW YORK CITY.
WEST 44th STREET AND AVENUE
OF THE AMERICAS.
BUT WHEN YOU REALLY STOP AND
LOOK AT IT FOR A WHILE, MAYBE
EVEN STARE AT IT, FRANKLY,
IT'S SCARY.
AS OF TODAY, EVERY HOUSEHOLD
IN THE UNITED STATES OWES
$140,000 OF DEBT.
EVERY SINGLE HOUSEHOLD.
THE U.S. BORROWED ROUGHLY
$6 BILLION EVERY DAY.
THE COUNTRY IS BORROWING
$239 BILLION EACH HOUR.
THAT IS $4 BILLION EVERY
MINUTE.
IN THE TIME THAT THIS STARTED,
U.S. HAS ALREADY BORROWED
ANOTHER $4 MILLION.
FOR EVERY DOLLAR THEY BROUGHT
IN, IT SPENT $200.06.
IT RUNS A DEFICIT.
DEFICIT IS A ONE-YEAR
SHORTFALL THAT HAS TO BE MADE
UP BY BORROWING.
THE NATIONAL DEBT TOTAL
ACCUMULATED DEBT IS THE SUM OF
ALL THE ANNUAL DEFICITS.
LESS ANY SURPLUS.
IT'S THE RUNNING COUNT.
WE HEAR POLITICIANS TALK ABOUT
DEFICITS AND THE DEBT ALL THE
TIME.
>> THE DEBT.
>> DEFICIT.
>> DEBT.
>> Bret: HOW TO GET
POLITICIANS TO COME TO SOME
AGREEMENT TO GET THE DEBT
CLOCK SLOW DOWN OR TICK BACK
THE OTHER WAY CONTINUES TO BE
THE CHALLENGE.
BUT FIRST, WHERE WE HAVE BEEN.
>> TAKE A LOOK AT THE DEBT
THROUGH HISTORY.
THE AMOUNT WE OWE EBBED AND
FLOWED.
OVER COUNTRY OF SPENDING MORE
THAN IT TAKES IN, IS NOTHING
NEW.
1835 SAW THE LOWEST RECORDED
DEBT AT $34,000 UNDER
PRESIDENT ANDREW JACKSON.
UNSUCCESSFUL ASSASSINATION
ATTEMPT ON HIM THAT YEAR.
1865, PRESIDENT THAT DID
PERISH FROM SUCH AN ATTACK,
PRESIDENT LINCOLN OVERSAW A
DEBT OF $3 BILLION.
>> BLACK TUESDAY, THE MOST
DEVASTATED STOCK MARKET CRASH
IN HISTORY OF THE UNITED
STATES, IT ROSE TO $17 BILLION
THEN.
THEN CAME WORLD WAR II.
EXPENSIVE ONE.
BY "D" DAY IN 1945, THE DEBT
BALLOONED TO $259 BILLION.
QUART ORE OF A TRILLION
DOLLARS.
MORE RECENT TIMES.
THE 2008 FINANCIAL CRISIS.
THE AMOUNT OF OUR DEBT OUR
COUNTRY HELD CROSSED THE
$10 TRILLION FIGURE FOR THE
FIRST TIME.
IT HAS CONTINUED TO RISE.
WHICH LEADS US TO WHERE WE ARE
NOW.
MORE THAN $16 TRILLION IN THE
HOLE AND COUNTING.
ECONOMISTS ROBERT GINETSKY
AUTHOR OF CLASSICAL ECONOMIC
NATION BELIEVES HISTORY SHOWS
WHEN THEY SPEND INCREASING
FASTER THAN THE OVERALL
ECONOMY, THE PRIVATE SECTOR
AND ECONOMY OVERALL SERVES.
>> 1945-1947, THERE WAS A HUGE
CUT IN GOVERNMENT SPENNING
BECAUSE OF WINDING DOWN FROM
WORLD WAR II.
THE PEOPLE WHO THOUGHT THE
GOVERNMENT SPENDING WAS
HOLDING THE ECONOMY UP WERE
ALL PREDICTING A MAJOR
DEPRESSION.
AT THAT TIME.
WHAT HAPPENED WAS FOR THE
FIRST TIME IN 15, 16 YEARS, A
HUGE INCREASE IN PRIVATE
SPENDING ON GOODS AND SERVICES
PER PERSON.
25% INCREASE IN TWO YEARS.
WHAT WAS HAPPENING IS THERE
WAS A SUBSTITUTE WITH THE
GOVERNMENT SPENDING ON DOWN.
MORE MONEY AND RESOURCES, FOR
PRIVATE SPENDING TO GO UP.
THAT IS THE REAL RECOVERY.
THE RECOVERY WASN'T WORLD WAR
II.
WHEN FIGHTING FOR OUR SURVIVAL
AND SPENDING MONEY TO A ASSURE
THE SURVIVAL.
>> MANY PEOPLE RAIL ABOUT THE
GOVERNMENT DOES TOO MUCH.
THEY WEATHER SAYING THE
GOVERNMENT HASN'T DONE ENOUGH.
WE HAVEN'T BEEN SPECIFIC ABOUT
THIS.
IT'S NOT DISCRETIONARY
SPENDING BUT THIS COMING
TSUNAMI OF OLDER PEOPLE WE
HAVE TO COPE WITH.
DOES IT HAVE TO GROW THAT
FAST?
I DON'T THINK IT DOES.
>> STANFORD ECONOMIST AND
AUTHOR OF "FIRST
PRINCIPLES: FIVE KEYS TO
RESTORING AMERICA'S
PROSPERITY" SAID BECAUSE OF
INTEREST TIME IS RUNNING OUT
TO DEAL WITH THE DEBT AND
DEFICIT.
>> SO MUCH THAT DEBT SUSPECT
SO LARGE IT'S SUSPICIOUS TO
PAY IT BACK.
>> MORTGAGE DEBT YOU PAY
INTEREST ON IT.
RIGHT NOW INTEREST RATES ARE
RELATIVELY LOW.
BUT THEY ARE BOUND TO GO UP IN
THE FUTURE.
SO THAT WILL MAKE THE INTEREST
PAYMENTS MUCH HIGHER.
IF WE DON'T CORRECT THIS
PROBLEM, INTERESTS WILL THE
END TO DOMINATE OUR SPENDING
GREATER THAN DEFENSE.
>> WE HAVE A HISTORY TO GUIDE
US.
THE DEBT GETS  TOO HIGH AND
PEOPLE ARE SKEPTICAL OF LEN
LENDING.
THEN WE HAVE A CRISIS.
IT'S DANGEROUS WHEN YOU GET
TOO HIGH AND MOVING CLOSE TO
THE DANGEROUS LEVEL EVERY DAY.
>> TOMORROW THE SERIES HOW
WASHINGTON CUTS SPENDING.
AND LATER IN THE WEEK, HOW THE
FEDERAL RESERVE FACTORS IN TO
THE THIS.
STOCKS WERE UP TODAY.
DOW ADDED 115.
THE S&P PICKED UP 16.
NASDAQ FINISHED AHEAD 44.
WANT TO OWN A PIECE OF
PRESIDENTIAL HISTORY?
WE TELL YOU HOW IN THE
GRAPEVINE.
UP NEXT, STUDENTS HEAD BACK TO
CLASSROOM IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
NEW DEMANDS FOR GUN CONTROL
LEGISLATION EMERGE IN
WASHINGTON.
I ALWAYS WAIT
UNTIL THE LAST MINUTE.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME R CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
to the number 1 club
in the world.
The potential of
Manchester United unlocked.
NYSE Euronext.
Unlocking the world's potential.
A Hybrid? Most are
just no fun to drive.
Now, here's one that will
make you feel alive.
Meet the five-passenger
Ford C-MAX Hybrid.
C-MAX says ha.
C-MAX says wheeee.
Which is what you get,
don't you see?
Cause C-MAX has lots more
horsepower than Prius v,
a hybrid that C-MAX
also bests in MPG.
Say hi to the all-new 47
combined MPG C-MAX Hybrid.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT STARTED LONG AGO.
THE JOY OF GIVING SOMETHING
EVERYTHING YOU'VE GOT.
IT TAKES PASSION.
AND IT'S NOT LETTING UP
ANYTIME SOON.
AT UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company,
WE UNDERSTAND THAT COMMITMENT.
AND ALWAYS HAVE.
SO DOES AARP,
AN ORGANIZATION
SERVING THE NEEDS
OF AMERICANS 50 AND OVER
FOR GENERATIONS.
SO IT'S NO SURPRISE
MILLIONS HAVE CHOSEN
AN AARP Medicare Supplement
Insurance Plan,
INSURED BY UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company.
LIKE ALL STANDARDIZED
MEDICARE SUPPLEMENT PLANS,
THEY HELP COVER
SOME OF THE EXPENSES
MEDICARE DOESN'T PAY.
AND SAVE YOU UP TO THOUSANDS
IN OUT-OF-POCKET COSTS.
TO FIND OUT MORE,
REQUEST YOUR
FREE DECISION GUIDE.
CALL OR GO ONLINE TODAY.
AFTER ALL,
WHEN YOU'RE GOING THE DISTANCE,
IT'S NICE TO HAVE
THE EXPERIENCE AND COMMITMENT
TO GO ALONG WITH YOU.
KEEP DREAMING. KEEP DOING.
GO LONG.
>> Bret: STUDENTS RETURN TO
CLASSES TODAY.
THEY WERE SENT TO MIDDLE
SCHOOL IN NEIGHBORING TOWN.
TWO MORE FUNERALS HELD FOR
CHILDREN KILLED IN THAT ATTAC
ATTACK.
SOME LAWMAKERS SUGGEST THE
PRESIDENT TAKE THE LEAD ON THE
ISSUE.
AT THE LEAST PUSH FOR
REINSTATING THE ASSAULT
WEAPONS BEEN A.
NOW THE NRA HAS WEIGHED IN.
CHIEF WASHINGTON CORRESPONDENT
JAMES ROSEN HAS THE STORY.
>> CHALLENGING DAYS AHEAD FOR
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> THE NATIONAL RIFLE
ASSOCIATION SOUGHT TO COUNTER
THE MASSIVE COORDINATED
CAMPAIGN FOR NEW LAWS BY GUN
CONTROL LOBBY.
>> YOU HAVE BLOOMBERG AND
SCHUMER AND FEINSTEIN
INSISTING WE NEED TOUGHER GUN
LAWS.
YOU LOOK AT CONNECTICUT ARE
NUMBER FIVE WITH THE STRICTEST
GUN LAWS IN THE COUNTRY.
>> SOURCES TELL FOX NEWS THE
NRA HAVING OBSERVED A PROPER
MOURNING PERIOD WILL BEGIN TO
PUSH BACK AGAINST GUN CONTROL
ADVOCATES.
WIDENING THE DISCUSSION TO
INCLUDE HOLLYWOOD AND GAMING
INDUSTRY.
AND PITTING DEFENDERS OF THE
FIRST AMENDMENT AGAINST THE
DEFENDERS OF THE SECOND.
LATE TODAY, THE NRA MADE A
MOVE TO ANNOUNCE A MAJOR NEWS
CONFERENCE FRIDAY AND SAYING
THE 4 MILLION MEMBERS, MALE
AND FEMALE PREPARED TO OFFER
MEANINGFUL CONTRIBUTIONS TO
MAKE SURE IT NEVER HAPPENS.
AGAIN WENT ON THE RECORD WITH
THE MEASURES THAT PRESIDENT
OBAMA FIGHTS FOR.
>> HE IS SUPPORTIVE OF SENATOR
FEINSTEIN'S STATED INTENT TO
REVIVE, A PIECE OF LEGISLATION
TO REINSTATE THE ASSAULT
WEAPON BEEN A.
HE SUPPORTS LEGISLATION TO
ADDRESS THE PROBLEM OF THE GUN
SHOW LOOPHOLE.
PEOPLE TALK ABOUT THE HIGH
CAPACITY AMMUNITION CLIPS FOR
EXAMPLE.
THAT IS SOMETHING THAT HE
WOULD BE INTERESTED IN LOOKING
AT.
>> SENATOR JOE MANCHIN THE GUN
FRIENDLY DEMOCRAT FROM WEST
VIRGINIA RE-ELECTED LAST MONTH
SPOKE BY PHONE WITH THE
PRESIDENT TODAY.
AFTERWARDS, URGED HIS NRA
FRIENDS TO NOT TO VILIFY THOSE
TALKING TO THE OTHER SIDE.
SAME TIME, THE DEMOCRATIC
SENATOR CLAIRE McCASKILL OF
MISSOURI.
ONE OF THE TOP TEN STATES FOR
GUN OWNERSHIP BACKGROUND CHECK
STRUCK A CONFRONTATIONM
POSTURE.
>> EVERYONE WALKS AROUND HERE,
TOO MANY, WORRIED ABOUT THE
NRA SCORE.
THEY SCORE, THEY SCORED
WHETHER OR NOT THE ATTORNEY
GENERAL WAS HELD IN CONTENT.
TWO WORDS FOR THE NRA.
SCORE THIS.
>> SENIOR OBAMA ADVISOR DAVID
AXELROD BLASTED OUT E-MAIL TO
CAMPAIGN SUPPORTERS YESTERDAY
THAT LINKED THEM TO A VIDEO OF
THE PRESIDENT EULOGY FROM THE
NEW TOWNSHIP VICTIM AT TWO
PLACES ALONGSIDE THE VIDEO
BOX.
VISITORS WERE ENCOURAGED TO
DONATE MONEY.
ONE ASKING FOR $5.
>> Bret: SEE HOW THAT GETS
REACTION ALL OVER.
JAMES, THANK YOU.
REPUBLICAN GOVERNOR RICK
SNYDER VETOED LEGISLATION TO
ALLOW CONCEALED WEAPONS IN
CHURCHES, SCHOOLS AND DAYCARE
CENTERS.
HE SAID THE PUBLIC VENUE NEED
CLEAR LEGAL AUTHORITY TO BEEN
A THE FIREARMS.
"IF THEY SEE FIT TO DO SO."
STILL AHEAD, IMAGINE FIVE DAYS
IN SYRIAN CAPTIVITY.
THE FOREIGN CORRESPONDENT
LIVED THROUGH IT.
LAWMAKERS AWAIT BENGHAZI
REVIEW.
[ whistle blows ]
HI VICTOR!
MOM?
I KNOW YOU GOT TO GO
IN A MINUTE
BUT THIS IS
A REAL QUICK ME,
THAT'S PERFECT FOR TWO!
CAMPBELL'S CHUNKY BEEF
WITH COUNTRY VEGETABLES,
POURED OVER RICE!
[ Male Announcer ]
CAMPBELL'S CHUNKY SOUP.
IT FILLS YOU UP RIGHT.
>> Bret: CHECKING
INTERNATIONAL HEADLINES NOW.
IN MEXICO, A NEW TWIST IN THE
FIGHT OF MARINE VETERAN JOHN
HAMMER WHO HAS BEEN IN A
MEXICAN PRISON FOR FOUR MONTHS
ON WHAT MANY CALL A TRUMPED UP
FEDERAL WEAPONS CHARGE.
HIS FAMILY RECEIVED A NEW
PHOTO OF HIM CHAINED TO A BED.
IN HIS PRISON CELL.
FROM ANONYMOUS E-MAIL.
THE FIRST PHOTO TAKEN SINCE HE
WAS LOCKED UP FOR TRYING TO
DECLARE AN ANTIQUE GUN AT THE
BORDER.
HAMMER IS SET TO APPEAR IN
COURT ON JANUARY 17.
WE ARE FOLLOWING THIS STORY.
THE STATE DEPARTMENT HAS BEGUN
TO IMPLEMENT RECOMMENDATIONS
TO IMPROVE SECURITY AT
U.S. DIPLOMATIC MISSIONS.
MOVE CALLED FOR BY AN
INDEPENDENT PANEL SET UP TO
INVESTIGATE THE SEPTEMBER 11
ATTACK IN BENGHAZI, LIBYA,
THAT KILLED A U.S. AMBASSADOR
AND THREE OTHER AMERICANS.
CATHERINE HERRIDGE HAS MORE.
>> CLASSIFIED REPORT ARRIVED
IN THE LAST MINUTES.
THEY ARE WAITING FOR THE
FINDING TO BE BRIEFED TOMORROW
IS CLASSIFIED HEARINGS FOR THE
HOUSE AND SENATE FOREIGN
RELATIONS COMMITTEE.
IN ADDITION TO WORKING ON
SYRIA AND NORTH KOREA, AIDES
TO SECRETARY CLINTON SAY SHE
IS DRAFTING A LETTER IN
RESPONSE TO FINDINGS MADE
AVAILABLE TO LAWMAKERS BEFORE
THE HEARINGS TOMORROW.
UNCLASSIFIED VERSION OF THE
REPORT COULD BE RELEASED AS
EARLY AS TONIGHT.
ONCE AGAIN, BRIEFING, THE
STATE DEPARTMENT TRIED TO
EXPLAIN WHY CLINTON IS NOT
TESTIFYING THIS WEEK ABOUT THE
BENGHAZI TERRORIST ATTACK,
WHICH KILLED FOUR AMERICANS
INCLUDING HER AMBASSADOR.
TODAY, THE STATE DEPARTMENT
OFFICIALS FIELDED MORE
QUESTIONS WILL THE SECRETARY
WELL KNOWN FOR HER WORK ETHIC
DODGING UNCOMFORTABLE
TESTIMONY.
>> COMPLETELY UNTRUE.
WE HAVE BEEN VERY CLEAR FROM
THE BEGINNING THAT SHE HAD A
STOMACH VIRUS.
UGLY STOMACH VIRUS.
SHE GOT VERY DEHYDRATED,
FAINTED.
LATER DISCOVERED.
>> PUBLIC HEARINGS THURSDAY,
DEPUTIES WILL TESTIFY IN HER
PLACE.
THE TESTIMONY WOULD BE WHAT
CLINTON WOULD SAY.
>> REMIND THAT THEY ARE
STANDING IN FOR HER.
SO THE TESTIMONY ON THURSDAY
WOULD REFLECT HER VIEW AND HOW
TO DO FORWARD FROM THE REPORT.
HOW TO LEARN ITS LESSONS.
>> NOT HAVING SEEN THE FINAL
REPORT, WHICH ALSO
INVESTIGATES THE MILITARY
RESPONSE TO BENGHAZI, DEFENSE
SECRETARY PANETTA SAID A
TERRORIST ASSAULT.
NO QUESTION EXTREMISTS WERE
INVOLVED IN THE ATTACK.
WE LEARNED A LOT AND WILL
CONTINUE TO FROM THE INCIDENT.
>> THE ADMINISTRATION BLAMED
THE FILM FOR INCITING THE
VIOLENCE.
>> MORE ON THIS WITH THE
PANEL.
>> SHOULD YOU TELL THE TRUTH
AT A TRAFFIC STOP?
IS THE WORLD IN THE FINAL
DAYS?
WELL, THAT DEPENDS ON WHO YOU
ASK.
GRAPEVINE IS NEXT.
TRY RUNNING FOUR.NING
A RESTAURANT IS HARD,
FORTUNATELY WE'VE GOT INK.
IT GIVES US 5X THE REWARDS
ON OUR INTERNET, PHONE
CHARGES AND CABLE,
PLUS AT OFFICE SUPPLY STORES.
REWARDS WE PUT RIGHT
BACK INTO OUR BUSINESS.
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
WE'VE EVER WANTED TO DO
AND INK HELPS US DO IT.
MAKE YOUR MARK
WITH INK FROM CHASE.
>> Bret: NOW FRESH PICKINGS
FROM THE POLITICAL GRAPEVINE,
SOME DOOMSDAYERS POINT TO
MAYAN CALENDAR, WE ONLY HAVE A
LITTLE LESS THAN THREE DAYS
UNTIL THE END OF THE WORLD.
CHINESE VILLAGER TRYING TO
MAKE A PROFIT BUILT HIS
VERSION OF NOAH'S ARK, TSUNAMI
PROOF SURVIVAL PODS, FOR
PEOPLE TRYING TO MAKE IT
THROUGH THE APOCALYPSE.
THEY'RE FIBER GLASS OVER A
STEEL FRAME, EQUIPPED WITH THE
OXYGEN TANK, FOOD, WATER AND
SEAT BELTS.
THEY ARE DESIGNED FOR 14
PEOPLE.
BUT 30 CAN SURVIVE INSIDE FOR
TWO MONTHS.
THEYCO $40,000 A PIECE.
THE AVERAGE SALARY FOR THE
PROVINCE OF CHINA IS UNDER
$6,000.
SO FAR NO, BUYERS.
OF COURSE NASA IS NOT BUYING A
POD OR THE APOCALYPSE, ITSELF.
THE IS SO CONFIDENT THAT THE
WORLD WILL NOT END FRIDAY, IT
RELEASED A DEBUNKING VIDEO
EARLY.
IT WAS INTENDED TO PLAY ON
DECEMBER 22.
ANOTHER GROUP NOT TAKING THE
END OF THE WORLD PRECAUTIONS
ARE THE MAYANS THEMSELVES.
DAILY LIFE CONTINUES AS MAYAN
POPULATION.
THEY SAID THE WORLD WILL END
BUT WE DON'T KNOW WHEN IT WILL
END.
PIECE OF HISTORY COULD BE
YOURS IF THE PRICE IS RIGHT.
PRESIDENT BUSH OFFERING OFF
THE F-150 PICKUP TRUCK USED ON
HIS RANCH IN TEXAS AFTER HIS
PRESIDENCY, DURING THE
PRESIDENCY.
THE PROCEEDS BENEFITING THE
FISHER HOUSE FOUNDATION, TO
ASSIST THE MILITARY FAMILIES.
GOOD NEWS ABOUT A TRAFFIC
TICKET.
WHEN DO YOU HEAR THAT?
CARLO POZ OWLED OVER IN -- WAS
PULLED OVER IN NORTH TEXAS HE
TOLD THE OFFICER HE HAD NO
EXCUSE OTHER THAN HE COULDN'T
AFFORD THE TICKET.
THE OFFICER LEFT HIM WITH A
CITATION, WARNING AND $100
BILL.
HE TOLD THE LOCAL POLICE
STATION HE HELPED ME OUT WHEN
I NEEDED IT AND I APPRECIATE
THAT.
I'LL NEVER FORGET THAT MAN.
HE USED THE MONEY PAY FOR HIS
AND HIS WIFE'S CAR
REGISTRATIONS.
GOODS NEWS.
>>> IN EGYPTIANS, THOUSANDS OF
PROTESTERS MARCHED IN THE
SQUARE TO PROTEST DRAFT
CONSTITUTION.
A CREW ESCAPED CAPTIVITY FROM
THE SYRIAN GUNMAN.
CORRESPONDENT LELAND VITTERT
HAS A PIDDLE EAST ROUNDUP.
>> ONCE THE HUNTED, SYRIAN
OUTGUNNED REBELS ARE BECOMING
THE HUNTER.
THEY APPEAR TO HAVE MORE
ORGANIZATION.
FIGHTERS ARE BETTER ARMED
THANKS TO QATAR AND ADVANCING
ON ME MASS CUSS.
-- MASSACRE.
EVIDENCED BY THE KIDNAPPING OF
THE CHIEF CORRESPONDENT
RICHARD ANGELE IN WHAT HE
THOUGHT WAS REBEL TERRITORY.
A NEWLY FREED CREW ARRIVED IN
TURKEY TO TELL A STORY OF THE
MOCK EXECUTION A THE
PSYCHOLOGICAL TORTURE BEFORE
AN ESCAPE FOR A FIREFIGHT.
>> THE LAST FIVE DAYS, ARE
DAYS WE WOULD RATHER FORGET.
>> ANGLE AND CREW HAD BEEN IN
THE TOWN OF ALEPPO WHERE A
STREET TO STREET BATTLE
CONTINUES FOR CONTROL.
PROVING THAT EVEN A
SUCCESSIONFUL REVOLUTION
DOESN'T SOLVE A COUNTRY'S
PROBLEM, SYRIANS WOULD ONLY
NEED TO LOOK TOWARD EGYPT,
WHERE A DRAFT CONSTITUTION HAS
SPARKED RENEWED VIOLENCE.
PROTESTS BETWEEN LIBERALS AND
THOSE WHO SUPPORT PRESIDENT
MORSI, MEMBER OF BROTHERHOOD.
UNOFFICIAL RESULTS SHOWING
LEANING TOWARD ISLAMISTS.
LIKE ALL, THERE ARE CHARGES OF
RAMPANT FRAUD.
TODAY, THERE WAS RESIGNATION
TO COMPLICATE THING FOR
SATURDAY WHEN THEY GO TO
BALLOT BOX FOR THE VOTE ON THE
CONSTITUTION.
THE ARAB SPRING ARE FAR FROM
OVER.
>> IN THE MIDDLE EAST,
TALIBANI SUFFERED A STROKE AND
WE'RE TOLD HE HAS SLIPPED IN
TO A COMA.
PRESIDENT'S MEDICAL TEAM IS
STABILIZING THE CONDITION.
HAS NOT DECIDED WHETHER OR NOT
TALABANI WILL CONTINUE TO BE
TREATED IN BAGHDAD OR THROWN
TO ANOTHER COUNTRY FOR
TREATMENT.
>> THE WHITE HOUSE REJECTED
BOEHNER PLAN "B."
WHAT NOW?
WHAT IS NEXT FOR THE FISCAL
CLIFF?
WE ASK THE PANEL AFTER THE
BREAK.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
JILL AND HER MOUTH HAVE LIVED
A GREAT LIFE.
BUT SHE HAS SOME DENTAL ISSUES
SHE'S NOT HAPPY ABOUT.
SO I INTRODUCED JILL
TO CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SELECTED FOR PEOPLE OVER 50.
PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE IS A
TOOTHPASTE THAT DEFENDS AGAINST
TENDER, INFLAMED GUMS,
SENSITIVITY AND WEAK ENAMEL.
CONDITIONS PEOPLE OVER 50
EXPERIENCE.
CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SO JILL CAN KEEP LIVING
THE GOOD LIFE.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
>>> EVERY TIME WE GET DOWN TO
DOING SOMETHING FOR THE
LONG-TERM FINANCIAL SECURITY
OF THIS COUNTRY, THEY TAKE
THAT FOOTBALL.
CHARLIE BROWN EPISODE, THEY
JERK THE BALL AWAY.
>> IT WOULD BE BETTER FOR
COUNTRY.
BUT AT THIS POINT, HAVING A
BACKUP PLAN TO MAKE SURE THAT
THE FEW AMERICAN TAXPAYERS
AFFECTED BY THE INCREASE AS
POSSIBLE.
MOVING DOWN THAT PATH IS THE
RIGHT COURSE OF ACTION FOR US.
>> PLAN "B."
HOUSE REPUBLICANS ARE EXPECTED
TO VOTE ON THIS, ON THURSDAY.
IT WOULD ESSENTIALLY KEEP
TAXES THE SAME FOR EVERYONE
BELOW $1 MILLION.
THERE ARE SOME REPUBLICANS WHO
HAVE A PROBLEM WITH THE TACTIC
ALREADY.
SOME OF THEM ARE WEIGHING IN.
>> ONCE YOU CROSS THAT LINE,
SOME PEOPLE, SOME PEOPLE --
[ INAUDIBLE ]
I THINK A LOT OF MEMBERS ARE
STRUGGLING WITH IT.
>> Bret: SOME REPUBLICANS
ARE NOT HAPPY WITH IT.
THE WHITE HOUSE TURNED IT
DOWN.
BUT NEGOTIATIONS ARE
CONTINUING.
SO WHERE ARE WE?
BRING IN THE PANEL.
TUCKER CARLSON, EDITOR OF THE
DAILYCALLER.COM.
A.B. STODDARD ASSOCIATE EDITOR
OF THE HILL.
AND SINDCATED COLUMNIST
CHARLES KRAUTHAMMER.
14 DAYS FROM TONIGHT.
BY THE WAY.
>> START OF THE DAY I WAS
FEELING OPTIMISTIC IN A WAY I
HAVE NOT.
IT SURPRISED ME BUT IT SEEMS
THAT THINGS ARE MOVING
QUICKLY.
THINGS ARE MOVING ON BOTH
SIDES.
THE WHITE HOUSE SAYING THIS IS
NOT THE FINAL OFFER.
BUT BY THE END OF THE TODAY
IT'S CLEAR THAT THE
REPUBLICANS-MEETING WITH THE
LEADERSHIP THIS MORNING AFTER
GETTING BACK IN TOWN, REALLY
WANT WHAT THEY ARE CALLING
VERIFIABLE SPENDING CUTS.
THEY WANT MORE ON THE SPENDING
SIDE.
THEY KNOW WHAT BOEHNER OFFERS
IN REVENUE, A LOT.
SHOCKING AMOUNT.
TO ANYONE EITHER SIDE.
IF YOU THOUGHT ABOUT THIS A
COUPLE OF MONTHS AGO.
BUT THEY WANT REAL ENTITLEMENT
REFORM.
THEY WANT NOT PROVIDER CUTS,
WHICH ARE NEVER FOLLOWED
THROUGH BY CONGRESS.
THEY WANT VERIFIABLE CUTS.
WHAT YOU HEAR FROM REPUBLICANS
IS WE HEARD THIS BEFORE.
WE PROMISE SPENDING CUTS THAT
DON'T COME THROUGH.
THEY DON'T WANT AN AMOUNT TO
REPLACE THE
THEY WANT AMOUNT ON TOP OF THE
SEQUESTER AND NEW CUTS TO
REPLACE SEQUESTER.
NOT WHAT THE WHITE HOUSE IS
OFFERING.
>> Bret: THE WHITE HOUSE IS
NOT OFFERING.
THEY ARE SAYING THEY ARE
WILLING TO GO ON THE TAX CUTS
UP TO $400,000 FROM $250,000.
BEING THE CAP.
UP TO $400,000.
BUT ON A SPENDING CUT SIDE,
FROM WHAT WE HEAR, WE HAVEN'T
HEARD ANYTHING NEW.
>> ON THE REVENUE SIDE, THE
SIDES ARE CLOSE.
MY READING OF IT.
REPUBLICANS CONCEDEED THEY
WILL BE FOR RAISING TAXES.
YOU COULD FIND HILARIOUS TAPE
SOMEWHERE OF CHUCK SCHUMER AND
BARBARA BOXER, BOTH ARGUING
THAT PEOPLE WHO MAKE $250,000
ARE NOT RICH.
SO BASICALLY, THE HOUSE
REPUBLICANS HAVE TAKEN THE
DEMOCRATIC PLAN ON REVENUE.
ON SPENDING, HOWEVER, THERE IS
A NEW DEFINITION.
WHITE HOUSE TODAY ATTACKED
HOUSE REPUBLICANS FOR NOT
CUTTING AND OBAMA HAS NO
INTENTION OF AND NO PLAN TO
SIGNIFICANTLY REDUCE THE
GROWTH OF GOVERNMENT OR REIGN
IN, ENTITLEMENT AT ALL.
REPUBLICANS KNOW.
THAT BY THE WAY, LOOK AT
DETAILS OF THE OBAMA PLAN.
A LOT OF "SAVINGS" ARE
PROJECTED REDUCTION IN
INTEREST ON THE NATIONAL DEBT.
THAT IS NOT REAL.
THAT IS PHONY.
THEY HAVEN'T MOVED AN INCH.
>> Bret: TO YOUR POINT ABOUT
THE DEMOCRATS AND WHAT THEY
SAID BEFORE, SENATOR
McCONNELL MENTIONED THAT THE
PLAN "B" CAME OUT ABOUT THE
MILLION DOLLARS AND UP.
AND HE TALKED ABOUT IT ON THE
FLOOR TODAY.
IN THE SUMMER OF 2010, SENATOR
SCHUMER SAID, "FIRST, I DON'T
KNOW A SINGLE ONE OF MY
COLLEAGUES WHO WOULDN'T PREFER
TO DO TAX BREAKS FOR PEOPLE UP
TO $1 MILLION.
THAT IS MY UNDERSTANDING THAT
THAT IS ESSENTIALLY THE
PROPOSAL THAT THE HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES SENT OVER TO
US LATER IN THE WEEK.
>> Bret: HARRY REID SAYING
IT HAS NO CHANCE IN THE
SENATE, CHARLES.
SO AGAIN, BACK AND FORTH AND
REPUBLICANS LOOK FOR ESCAPE
HATCH SO THEY HAVE A WAY OUT
TO KIND OF POLITICALLY BE
PROTECTED TO SAY HEY, LISTEN
WE PASS THIS.
AND IT INCLUDES TAX INCREASE
EVEN ON MILLIONAIRES.
>> BOEHNER HAS GIVEN SO MUCH
ON THE TAXATION.
HE IS REALLY AT RISK OF GOING
OVERBOARD.
UNLESS HE HAS SERIOUS STUFF ON
SPENNING.
THEY GOT SWINDLED ON SPENDING.
HE SAID, IN FACT, REAGAN SAID
HE CUT A DEAL WHERE HE RAISED
THE TAXES.
HE WAS PROMISED $3 A SPENDING
CUT FOR EVERY DOLLAR OF TAXES
RAISED.
HE GOT NOTHING.
HE SAID IT WAS THE BIGGEST
POLITICAL REGRET HE HAD.
THIS IS THE FOOTBALL AND
CHARLIE BROWN ALL OVER AGAIN.
BOEHNER PROBABLY MADE A
MISTAKE CAVING ON RATES.
BUT THAT IS DONE.
IF HE WERE TO START ALL OVER,
HE PROBABLY WOULD HAVEN'T OR
SHOULD HAVE.
BUT THEY GAVEED ON RATE.
THIS PLAN "B," REPUBLICANS IN
THE HOUSE WILL RAISE TAXES
OVER $1 MILLION.
WE KNOW THAT IS WHAT THE
DEMOCRATS AND SCHUMER PROPOSED
AND UTTER HYPOCRISY.
THE SPEAKER'S PLAN COULD BE
APPROACHED AND IT DOESN'T MEET
THE TEST OF PROTECTING THE
MIDDLE CLASS.
THINK ABOUT HOW IT YOTIC THAT
IS.
THAT PROTECTS THE MIDDLE CLASS
AND EVERYBODY UP TO
$1 MILLION.
BUT HE SAYS IT CAN'T PROTECT
THE MIDDLE CLASS BECAUSE THE
DEMOCRATS WILL REJECT IT, SO
NOT ENABLE IT TO PROTECT THE
MIDDLE CLASS.
THIS ISN'T ENOUGH.
IF YOU HAVE TO SAY STUFF LIKE
THAT.
>> THE SENATE WOULD SHOOT IT
DOWN FOR POLITICS.
BUT IT WOULD PROTECT MIDDLE
CLASS BECAUSE THE TAXES
WOULDN'T GET RAISED AND IT
WOULD BE RAISED ON THOSE
MAKING --
>> OVER $1 MILLION.
BUT THE ARGUMENT IS IT'S NOT
GOING TO HELP THE MIDDLE
CLASS, BECAUSE WE'LL KILL IT
BEFORE IT HELPS THE MIDDLE
CLASS.
>> Bret: SO DOESN'T THAT, IF
THE REPUBLICANS THEN VOTE THIS
THROUGH, DOESN'T THAT PUT ONUS
ON THE WHITE HOUSE?
>> YES.
THEY WILL PUT THE DEMOCRATS ON
THE DEFENSIVE.
>> CAN BOEHNER GET 218 VOTES
ON --
>> THAT IS WHAT TODAY IS
ABOUT.
THEY HOPE TO DO IT BY
THURSDAY.
DEMOCRATS SAY THEY WON'T HELP
HIM.
THIS IS AN ATTEMPT TO SAY WE
DIDN'T WANTBE TO GO OVER THE
CLIFF.
HELP THE MIDDLE CLASS.
NOT GOING TO GIVE ENTITLEMENT.
BIG FIGHT FOR JANUARY AND PUT
ONUS ON THE PRESIDENT.
>> CAN CONSERVATIVES SAY OKAY,
WELL --
>> KEEP IN MIND, THIS IS NOT
JUST INCOME.
CAPITAL GAIN AND DIVIDENDS
SNORE BUT CAN HE CONVINCE THEM
HAVE THE BATTLE IN THE NEW
YEAR, USE THE DEBT CEILING AS
LEVERAGE AND SPENDING CUT.
>> REPLACING THE COMMITTEE
CHAIRMAN IS A SIGN THAT HE HAS
PRETTY GOOD CONTROL OF THE
CAUCUS I SAY.
ON THE OTHER HAND, EVERY TIME
YOU GO UP THE HILL YOU HEAR
GROUSING ABOUT THE SPEAKER.
BITTER GROUSING FROM
CONSERVATIVES.
>> GIVEN A DEAL WHERE OBAMA
OFFERS NOTHING ON SPENDING OR
PLAN "B" WHERE YOU PASS TAX
INCREASE FOR $1 MILLION, YOU
HAVE TO GO TO PLAN "B."
MUCH SMART EVERY OPTION.
PLAN "A" IS ABSURD.
>> Bret: THREE CHOICES DOWN
THE ROW.
DEAL, PLAN "B" OR OVER THE
CLIFF?
>> OVER THE CLIFF.
>> I THINK IT'S LIKELY PLAN
"B."
SMALL HOPE FOR PLAN "A."
>> IF YOU THINK THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT CONSUMES LARGE
PROPORTION OF GDP YOU ARE OVER
THE CLIFF.
>> Bret: WHAT ARE YOU
PREDICTING?
>> OH, WHAT AM I -- SORRY.
WHAT AM I PREDICTING?
I THINK THERE IS A DEAL.
BOTH SIDES HAVE INTEREST TO
REACH IS AND THEY WILL.
>> NEXT UP, BENGHAZI REPORT UP
ON CAPITOL HILL NOW AND
HEARINGS WILL BE HELD WITHOUT
SECRETARY CLINTON.
PANEL WEIGHS IN ON THAT NEXT.
[ Male Announcer ]
RED LOBSTER'S CRABFEST
ENDS SOON.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OURENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
[ coughs ]
[ baby crying ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
ROBITUSSIN® LIQUID FORMULA
SOOTHES YOUR THROAT ON CONTACT
AND THE ACTIVE INGREDIENT
RELIEVES YOUR COUGH.
ROBITUSSIN®. DON'T SUFFER
THE COUGHEQUENCES™.
>> WE HAVE BEEN VERY CLEAR
FROM THE BEGINNING THAT SHE
HAD A STOMACH VIRUS, UGLY
STOMACH VIRUS, SHE GOT VERY
DEHYDRATED, SHE PAINTED.
LATER DISCOVERED HE IS HAD CON
SUGGESTION.
SHE WORKING AT HOME THIS WEEK.
ON THE MEND, GOING TO BE FINE.
SHE IS WORKING FROM HOME.
SHE GOT THE ARB REPORT
YESTERDAY AND READ THROUGH IT
YESTERDAY.
WORKING ON THE LETTER TO GO
WITH IT TO THE HILL.
ON THE PHONE AND E-MAIL
CONTACT WITH SENIOR STAFF.
>> Bret: SECRETARY CLINTON
REVIEWING THE ARB REPORT, THE
INDEPENDENT PANEL REPORT ON
THE BENGHAZI, LIBYA, ATTACK UP
ON CAPITOL HILL RIGHT NOW.
AHEAD OF CLASSIFIED HEARINGS
THIS WEEK.
TWO DEPUTY SECRETARIES WILL
TESTIFY IN HER STEAD AFTER
THAT VIRUS AND CONCUSSION
TALKED ABOUT AT THE STATE
DEPARTMENT THIS WEEK.
YOU CAN SEE THE DEPUTY
SECRETARY BURNS.
WE'RE BACK WITH THE PANEL.
WHAT ABOUT THIS?
THE WHOLE ISSUE?
CHARLES?
>> FORMER U.N. AMBASSADOR JOHN
BOLTON CALLS THIS A DIPLOMATIC
ILLNESS.
WE HEARD FROM VICTORIA NOONAN
IT'S A BAD BUG.
BENGHAZI ALLERGY.
SHE HAS A VE VEER BENGHAZI
ALLERGY.
FIVE DAYS AFTER THE ATTACK SHE
WAS NOT THERE TO ADDRESS THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE AND SHE SENT
OUT SOMEONE WHOM THE PRESIDENT
HIMSELF HAD NO IDEA WAS NOT
INVOLVED AT ALL IN BENGHAZI.
NOW THAT SHE IS SUPPOSED TO
SPEAK TO THE CONGRESS ABOUT
THIS.
SHE HAS ILLNESS.
I'M NOT GOING TO SAY SHE
DOESN'T HAVE ONE.
BE HAPPY TO GIVE HER
NEUROLOGICAL EXAM, AND ABSENCE
OF THAT I TAKE HER WORD.
BUT THERE IS SOMETHING STRANGE
ABOUT THIS.
SHE DID SAY OSTENTATIOUSLY, I
TAKE FULL RESPONSIBILITY FOR
THE ATTACK IN BENGHAZI.
SHE SAID THAT DURING THE
CAMPAIGN, WHICH IS COMPLETELY
AND UTTERLY MEANINGLESS.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
IN BRITAIN, INVASION OF
FALKENS, THE FORMER SECRETARY
RESIGNED OVER IT, THOUGH IT
WASN'T HIS FAULT.
AS A MATTER OF PRINCIPLE.
IF IT HAPPENS ON YOUR WATCH,
YOU RESIGN.
THAT ISN'T GOING TO HAPPEN IN
HER CASE, BUT SHE WON'T EVEN
SPEAK ABOUT IT, WHICH OUGHT TO
BE THE MINIMAL REQUIREMENT.
THAT IS INCUMBENT ON HER TO
DO.
>> Bret: A.B., THEY HAVE
SAYING SHE IS OPEN TO
TESTIFYING.
SCHEDULING ISSUE NOW.
ONCE YOU GET IN JANUARY, YOU
ARE IN TO A NEW CONGRESS.
AND WHAT ABOUT THAT
POSSIBILITY?
>> SHE WON'T BE --
>> Bret: SHE WON'T BE
SECRETARY OF STATE.
>> RIGHT.
THERE ARE PEOPLE OF ACCUSING
HER OF LYING TO SAY THIS IS A
FAKE CONCUSSION.
I THINK IT WOULD BE REALLY
HARD TO FAKE A CONCUSSION AND
HAVE IT ACTUALLY BE LEAKED TO
THE PRESS SOMEHOW THAT THE
WHOLE STORY WAS CON OCTOBE CONC.
THAT WOULD BE QUITE BRAZEN.
BUT SHE HAS BEEN CONSPICUOUSLY
ABSENT FROM ANY SITUATION
SINCE SEPTEMBER 11 WHERE SHE
WOULD HAVE TO TALK ABOUT IT.
ABSENT.
SHE DID MAKE A COMMENT ABOUT
SUSAN RICE BUT ABSENT
DEFENDING HER, ABSENT FROM
GIVING AN "OF WHAT HAPPENED --
GIVING AN ACCOUNT OF WHAT
HAPPENED WITH THE EXCEPTION
THAT SHE WANTED TO MAKE A
STATEMENT OF BEING FULLY
ACCOUNTABLE.
SHE IS EXAMINING THE PROSPECT
FOR FUTURE.
SHE IS CONSIDERED THE FRONT
RUNNER 2016 IN BOTH PARTIES.
AHEAD OF EVEN THE REPUBLICAN
PROSPECTS IN THE NEXT
PRESIDENTIAL CYCLE.
ANY TESTIMONY IS TOUGH
EXPERIENCE.
PUTTING IT OFF UNTIL JANUARY
WILL SOFTEN THE BLOW.
SHE HAS TO DO IT.
I'M NOT SAYING SHE IS LYING
BUT IT'S AWKWARD.
>> Bret: THIS REPORT WILL
GIVE US SOME STIR.
IT'S A CLASSIFIED HEARING.
>> IT COMES OUT TOMORROW.
KEEP IN MIND, I'M NOT IN A
POSITION AND I CAN'T ASSESS
HER CURRENT CONDITION.
BUT IN SEPTEMBER YOU WILL
REMEMBER, IF YOU WENT TO LOOK
BACK AT THE WORDING SHE SAID
SHE COULDN'T SPEAK OF BENGHAZI
BECAUSE SHE HAD A GRUELING
WEEK.
IT DOES STRAIN CREDULITY.
THIS IS ABOUT THE
ADMINISTRATION POLICY TOWARD
THE ARAB AND ISLAMIC WORLD
THIS WHICH HAS SEEN IN FOUR
YEARS THE RESURGENCE OF THE
ISLAMIC ACTIVITY IN KEY BIG
COUNTRIES.
EGIANT, SYRIA, LIB YEAH.
I AM NOT SUGGESTING THAT THE
WHITE HOUSE IS RESPONSIBLE FOR
THAT BUT I AM SUBJECTING A
SMART PERSON COULD ASK
PENETRATING QUESTIONS OF THE
EFECT OF THE POLICY, NONE OF
WHICH BORN FRUIT TO HELP US.
SHE DOESN'T WANT TO DEAL WITH
THAT.
AT SOME POINT, SHE SHOULD HAVE
TO.
THE LEFT SAYS SUSAN RICE THING
WAS A SIDESHOW.
THEY ARE KIND OF RIGHT.
SHE IS THE SECRETARY OF STATE.
SHE IS RESPONSIBLE.
>> Bret: THAT IS IT FOR THE
PANEL BUT STAY TUNED TO SEE AN
EFFORT AT HANDLING TOUCHY
QUESTIONS.
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
I GOT YOUR
CAMPBELL'S CHUNKY SOUP.
MOM?
WHO'S MOM?
I'M THE GIANTS MASCOT.
THE GIANTS DON'T HAVE
A MASCOT!
OHHH! EAT UP!
NEW JAMMIN JERK CHICKEN SOUP
HAS TASTY PIECES OF CHICKEN
WITH RICE AND BEANS.
HMMM.
FOR GIANT HUNGER!
THANKS MOM!
SEE YA!
WHOAA...OOPS!
MOM?
I'M OK.
GRANDMA?
HI SWEETIE!
SHE OPERATES THE HEAD.
Male Announcer ]
CAMPBELL'S CHUNKY SOUP.
IT FILLS YOU UP RIGHT.
AND HIS NEW BOSS TOLD HIM
TWO THINGS --
COOK WHAT YOU LOVE,
AND SAVE YOUR MONEY.
JOE DOESN'T KNOWT YET,
BUT HE'LL WORK HIS WAY UP
FROM BUSSER TO WAITER TO CHEF
BEFORE OPENING A RESTAURANT
SPECIALIZING IN FISH AND GAME
FROM THE GREAT NORTHWEST.
HE'LL START INVESTING EARLY,
HE'LL FIND SOME GOOD PEOPLE
TO HELP GUIDE HIM,
AND HE'LL SET MONEY ASIDE
FROM HIS FIRST DAY OF WORK
TO HIS LAST,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
>> FINALLY, THE JUSTICE
DEPARTMENT