>> ZBLUIG NEW DELEGATES EMERGE
CAN.
WHEN WAS ALL OVER, 20 CHILDREN
AND SEVEN ADULTS WERE DEAD.
GUNMAN KILLED HIMSELF.
I'M GREGG JARRETT.
THIS IS A BRAND-NEW HOUR.
>> Heather: I'M HEATHER
CHILDERS.
NEWS CONFERENCE THAT WRAPPED UP
MOMENTS AGO.
CHIEF MEDICAL EXAMINER SAYING
THAT MANY OF THE VICTIMS WERE
KILLED BY MULTIPLE CLOSE RANGE
GUNSHOTS.
HERE IS NEW PICTURE OF THE
SUSPECTED GUNMAN, ADAM LANZA AND
FRIENDS AND FAMILY DESCRIBE HIM
AS A STRANGER AND A LONER.
LAW ENFORCEMENT SOURCES SAY HE
SUFFERED FROM A MULTIPLE OR
PERSONALITY DISORDER.
NOW, THE FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS
SHATTERED COMMUNITY AND
GRIEF-STRICKEN NATION ARE COMING
TO GRIPS TODAY WITH THIS
HORRIFIC TRAGEDY.
AS POLICE SAY THEY ARE CLOSING
IN ON WHAT POSSIBLY CAUSED THE
GUNMAN TO FORCE HIS WAY INTO
THAT SCHOOL YESTERDAY AND OPEN
FIRE BEFORE TURNING THE GUN ON
HIMSELF.
TOWN OFFICIALS ASK FOR PRIVACY
AND RESPECT FOR THE VICTIMS'
FAMILIES.
>> NEWTOWN HAS SUFFERED A
HORRENDOUS TRAGEDY.
OUR WOUND IS DEEP BECAUSE WE ARE
CLOSE-KNIT COMMUNITY.
WE TRULY CARE FOR EACH OTHER.
WE ARE COMING TOGETHER WITH LOVE
AND SUPPORTED FOR THOSE FAMILIES
WHO HAVE SUFFERED THIS TERRIBLE
LOSS.
WE ARE STRONG AND CARING PLACE.
WE WILL PUT OUR ARMS AROUND
THOSE FAMILIES AND AROUND EACH
OTHER.
WE WILL FIND A WAY TO HEAL SO
THAT ALL OF OUR RESIDENTS, YOUNG
AND OLD WILL AGAIN FIND PEACE.
>> Heather: MOLLY IS LIVE WITH
THE VERY LATEST.
>> Reporter: AS YOU MIGHT EXPECT
LISTENING TO THE PRESS
CONFERENCE AND INFORMATION FROM
THE STATE MEDICAL EXAMINER'S
OFFICE IS DISTURBING.
AS YOU MENTIONED EACH OF THE
CHILDREN AND THE ADULTS THAT
WERE KILLED SUFFERED MULTIPLE
GUNSHOT WOUNDS ALL OVER THEIR
BODIES.
THERE WASN'T A PARTICULAR BODY
PART THAT THE MEDICAL EXAMINER
WAS HIT IN ANY OF THESE
PARTICULAR CASES.
ONLY A FEW WERE KILLED AT CLOSE
RANGE.
IT WAS A HORRIFIC SCENE AND
PERHAPS THE WORST HE HAS SCENE
AND COMRADES HAVE SEEN.
TO WORK THROUGHOUT THE NIGHT
WELL INTO THE DARK AS TO HELP
BRING CLOSURE TO IDENTIFY EACH
OF THESE CHILDREN AND THEIR
TEACHERS AND PEOPLE THAT WORKED
AT THE SCHOOL AND BE ABLE TO
OFFER THE FAMILIES KNOWLEDGE OF
THEIR LOVED ONE IN THE BUILDING.
TAKE A LISTEN.
THIS IS THE CHIEF MEDICAL
EXAMINER.
>> EVERYBODY'S DEATH WAS CAUSED
BY, EVERYONE THAT WE HAVE
COMPLETED SO FAR WAS CAUSED BY
GUNSHOT WOUNDS.
OBVIOUSLY THE MANNER OF DEATH ON
ALL THESE CASES IS HOMICIDE.
>> Reporter: AUTHORITIES ALSO
RELEASED THE LIST OF NAMES AND
BIRTH DATES.
WE'RE TILL STILL LOOKING AT THAT
LIST.
MAJORITY OF THE CHILDREN ON THE
LIST APPEAR TO BE GIRLS AND MOST
OF THE CHILDREN WERE BORN IN
2005 OR 2006.
THERE ARE THE NAMES OF THE
ADULTS THAT WERE KILLED WERE
RELEASED, AS WELL.
WE'RE WORKING ON COMPILING ALL
THOSE NAMES WHEN WE CAN HERE IN
THE FEW MOMENTS.
PART OF THE THING THAT MADE THIS
SO DISTURBING.
STATE MEDICAL EXAMINER WHAT THE
KIDS WERE WEARING.
AVERAGE OUTFIT YOU EXPECT TO BE
WEARING WHEN THEY HEAD OFF TO
FIRST GRADE.
MAJORITY OF THE CHILDREN WERE IN
THE FIRST GRADE AND THEN
LIEUTENANT WHO BROUGHT US SO
MUCH INFORMATION GAVE US A FEW
MORE DETAILS AND CLARIFIED A FEW
OF THE THINGS THAT HAVE BEEN
RELEASED.
WHEN IT COMES TO THE WEAPONS,
INITIALLY IT WAS REPORTED THERE
WERE TWO WEAPONS FOUND INSIDE
THE SCHOOL AND THEN FEDERAL
AUTHORITIES SAID THERE WERE
THREE.
HE COULDN'T CLARIFY AND HE WAS
WORKING TO DO THAT TOMORROW.
AS FAR AS AN ALTERCATION
CONCERNED THERE WERE REPORTS
THAT THE ALLEGED SHOOTER, ADAM
LANZA HAD GONE TO THE SCHOOL THE
DAY BEFORE.
THERE WAS SOME SORT OF
ALTERCATION.
THE LIEUTENANT SAID THERE IS NO
INFORMATION REGARDING THAT
ALTERCATION.
HE DOESN'T HAVE ANY INFORMATION
ABOUT THAT ACTUALLY OCCURRING.
ALSO THE MOTHER NANCY WHO WAS
SHOT THERE WERE REPORTS THAT SHE
WORKED AT THE SCHOOL.
THE LIEUTENANT SAYS THAT DOESN'T
APPEAR TO BE THE CASE.
>> Heather: THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> Gregg: ACCORDING TO POLICE,
SUSPECTED SCHOOL SHOOTER ADAM
LANZA GUNNED DOWN HIS OWN MOTHER
BEFORE HEADING TO SCHOOL.
NEW REPORTS REVEALING THAT
INVESTIGATORS HAVE NOT BEEN ABLE
TO FIND ANY LINK BETWEEN NANCY
LANZA AND SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN.
JOINING US ON THE PHONE IS
NANCY'S NEIGHBOR RHONDA COLLINS.
THANK YOU FOR TAKING A FEW
MOMENTS.
I UNDERSTAND YOU LIVE ABOUT A
BLOCK AWAY.
DID YOU SEE HER OFTEN AND
ENCOUNTERED HER OCCASIONALLY.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL US.
>> WHEN SHE FIRST MOVED INTO OUR
NEIGHBORHOOD I THINK IT WAS
PROBABLY AROUND 1998.
SHE JOINED A GROUP, WE GOT
TOGETHER EACH MONTH AND PLAYED
ON SOCIAL LEVEL.
SO I KIND OF KNEW HER FROM THAT.
OVER THE YEARS WE STOPPED
PLAYING AND OCCASIONALLY RUN
INTO HER AT GROCERY STORE.
>> Gregg: SHE WAS A PLEASANT
PERSON?
>> SHE WAS, VERY FRIENDLY AND
ONE OF THE NEIGHBORS.
A REGULAR PERSON.
SHE WAS JUST ONE OF US.
VERY NICE AND FRIENDLY.
>> Gregg: WHAT ABOUT ADAM LANZA,
DID YOU EVER SEE HIM?
>> NO, I DON'T REMEMBER MEETING
HER BOYS OR HER HUSBAND.
WE WOULD SEE HER AT.
>> YOU WERE AT MUNICIPAL CENTER
WHEN ALL OF THIS UNFOLDED
YESTERDAY.
AS I UNDERSTAND IT IT THEN WENT
INTO LOCKDOWN.
WHAT HAPPENED?
>> REPORTS STARTED COMING IN
ABOUT THERE HAD BEEN A SHOOTING
AT SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
SOMEONE CAME OUT AND RHONDA,
WHERE ARE YOUR KIDS, THEY WERE
AT HOME.
THEY WENT TO SANDY HOOD GRADE
SCHOOL WHEN THEY WERE YOUNG AND
THEY WERE IN COLLEGE AND
FINISHED FINALS.
I RAN TO MY FRIENDS THAT WERE
HELPING ME.
AND START PRAYING THERE HAS BEEN
A SHOOTING.
THEY STARTED LOCKING DOWN THE
DOORS AND BITS AND PIECES KEPT
COMING THROUGH.
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHAT WAS
HAPPENING.
MAYBE THEY THOUGHT THERE WAS A
SECOND SHOOTER, THAT IS WHY THEY
WENT INTO LOCK DOWN.
WHAT HE WOULD BE DEALING WITH.
ONE OF THE GUYS CAME OUT, I JUST
CALLED AND HAD THE FAMILY LOCK
MY DOORS.
I CALLED MY FAMILY, LOCK YOUR
DOORS.
THEY WERE SEARCHING OUR
NEIGHBORHOOD IN CASE THERE WAS
SOMEBODY WHO HAD COME BACK OVER
THIS WAY.
>> Gregg: SINCE YOUR SON WENT TO
THE SCHOOL YOU KNOW SOME OF THE
TEACHERS THERE?
>> THEY HAVEN'T BEEN AT SANDY
HOOK FOR EIGHT YEARS, BUT IN THE
EIGHT YEARS MY KIDS WENT THERE,
I VOLUNTEERED THERE A LOT.
I WAS THERE ALMOST DAILY HELPING
OUT WITH THE DIFFERENT
CLASSROOMS AND PUBLISHING
CENTER.
I MY MANY OF THE STAFF THAT ARE
STILL THERE AND TEACHERS.
IT WAS VERY NICE ENVIRONMENT.
NICE SCHOOL, EVERYBODY KNEW
EVERYBODY.
WE ALL LOOKED OUT FOR EVERYBODY.
IT'S HEARTBREAKING TO SEE WHAT
HAS HAPPENED THERE.
>> Gregg: RHONDA CULLENS OUR
CONDOLENCES TO EVERYBODY THERE
IN NEWTOWN.
>> I APPRECIATE ALL OF YOUR
PRAYERS.
>> Heather: WORD OF THE SHOOTING
SENDING SHOCK WAVES THROUGH THE
QUIET COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN WHERE
JUST ABOUT EVERYONE KNOWS
SOMEONE.
HERE IS MORE FROM FRIENDS AND
NEIGHBORS.
>> PARENTS' WORST NIGHTMARE
SAYING YOUR CHILD IS NOT COMING
HOME.
WHEN THEY FIRST CAME HOME FROM
SCHOOL, GIVE THEM THE BIGGEST
HUG I COULD.
I'M GRATEFUL THAT SHE IS HERE.
OUR HEARTS GO OUT TO THE
FAMILIES.
>> WHEN WE WERE AT SCHOOL, WE
WERE TOLD SANDY HOOK SCHOOL AND
WE HAD TO GO TO LOCKDOWN.
I COULD THINK, WAS MY OLD
SCHOOL.
I HAVE MANY FRIENDS THERE.
I WAS TERRIFIED BECAUSE I DIDN'T
KNOW WHAT WAS GOING ON.
THEY SAID AN INCIDENT AND AN
EMERGENCY SITUATION.
>> COUPLE MONTHS AGO WE HAD
TRICK-OR-TREAT IN OUR TOWN
AND...
.
>> Heather: SO CLOSE TO
CHRISTMAS AND IN THE MIDDLE OF
HANUKKAH, SOME PEOPLE ARE TAKING
DOWN DECORATIONS, TELLING
REPORTERS THEY FEEL GUILTY ABOUT
CELEBRATING THE HOLIDAY.
THAT IS UNDERSTANDABLE.
>> Gregg: OUT OF THIS TRAGEDY,
COUNTLESS HEROIC STORIES FROM
STAFF MEMBERS.
SEVERAL OF THEM SACRIFICING
THEMSELVES IN AN ATTEMPT TO SAVE
THE LIVES OF THE STUDENTS.
TEACHERS QUICKLY REACTING THE
MOMENT THEY HEARD THE FIRST
SHOTS.
MANY OF THEM LOCKING CLASSROOM
DOORS AND HIDING CHILDREN IN
BATHROOMS AND CLOSET.
ONE TEACHER READING STORIES TO
KEEP THE KIDS CALM.
ANOTHER TEACHER WAS 27-YEAR-OLD
VICTORIA SOTO, A YOUNG FIRST
GRADE TEACHER WHO DIED SAVING
HER STUDENTS.
COLLEAGUES ALSO SET SAID THE
PRINCIPAL NEVER HESITATED A
MOMENT AS MANY TEACHERS RAN INTO
THE HALLWAY STRAIGHT FOR THE
GUNMAN.
THAT MOVE ENDED UP COSTING HER
HER LIFE.
THE LIBRARY CLERK SAYS THEY
WOULD NOT OPEN UP THE DOORS
UNTIL THEY WERE ABSOLUTELY SURE
IT WAS SAFE.
>> WE DIDN'T KNOW, WE WOULDN'T
LET THEM IN AT FIRST.
THEY HAD SOMEONE CALL US AND PUT
A BADGE UNDER THE DOOR AND THAT
IS WHEN WE MOVED THE FILE
CABINETS AND LET THE KIDS OUT.
>> TO HONOR THEIR BRAVERY.
>> TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN RAISING
SERIOUS QUESTIONS ABOUT SCHOOL
SECURITY.
STATE POLICE CONFIRMING THAT THE
GUNMAN WAS NOT VOLUNTARILY LET
INTO THE SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
INSTEAD HE FORCED HIS WAY IN.
MOMENTS LATER HE OPENED FIRE AND
POLICE PUT OUT THIS DISPATCH
CALL.
>> CALLER IS INDICATING SHE
THINKS THERE IS SOMEBODY
SHOOTING IN THE BUILDING.
FRONT GLASS HAS BEEN...
>> Heather: OFFICERS RECOVERED
THREE WEAPONS INCLUDING A
BUSHMASTER SEMI-AUTOMATIC RIFLE
AND TWO HANDGUNS.
JOINING US NOW ON THE PHONE IS
BILL DAILY, A FORMER F.B.I.
INVESTIGATOR AND SENIOR ADVISOR
FOR CONTROL RISK SECURITY.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR JOINING
US.
I WANT TO BEGAN WITH THE SCHOOL
SECURITY THERE AT SANDY HOOK.
THE PRINCIPAL APPARENTLY HAVING
INITIATED HERSELF ADDITIONAL
SECURITY MEASURES AT THE SCENE.
HOW MIGHT THIS INCIDENT CHANGE
ON A NATIONAL LEVEL THE WAY THAT
SCHOOL SAFETY SHOULD BE
IMPLEMENTED?
>> IT IS VERY TRAGIC THAT
INCIDENTS LIKE THIS MUCH LIKE
EVERY OTHER SECURITY INCIDENT
MOVES TOWARD A CONTINUUM WHERE
PEOPLE ARE THINKING A LITTLE
DIFFERENT ABOUT SECURITY.
IT SOUNDED TO ME THAT THE SCHOOL
HAD PUT A BUZZER SYSTEM AND
LOCKED DOWN THE DOOR, IT SOUNDS
PRUDENT.
NOW, WE KNOW OR BELIEVE THIS
PERPETRATOR BROKE THROUGH THE
GLASS AND MADE HIS WAY IN.
THE WHOLE IDEA OF SECURITY IS
JUST PROVIDE SOME DELAY.
ANY PERSON INTENT ON GETTING
INTO A FACILITY WILL GET THERE.
WE WANTED TO DELAY THAT ACTIVITY
TO GIVE MORE TIME FOR POLICE TO
ARRIVE.
I THINK WHAT THEY DID UP IN THAT
SCHOOL WAS VERY PRUDENT FOR
CONDITIONS.
IT OPENS UP A NATIONAL DIALOGUE
TOWARDS HOW WE SHOULD BE LOOKING
AT SCHOOLS NO MATTER WHERE THEY
ARE.
COLUMBINE WAS ONE INDICATION OF
THINGS THAT SCHOOLS NEED TO BE
LOOKING AT.
I THINK AFTER THIS, THEY WILL BE
LOOKED AT IN MORE BROAD FASHION.
>> WHAT IT TELLS ME, THEY TRIED
TO DO EVERYTHING THEY COULD TO
STOP SOMETHING LIKE THIS FROM
HAPPENING.
CAN WE EVER DO ENOUGH?
>> WE ALL WOULD LIKE TO DO
ENOUGH AND SAVE EVERY LIFE THERE
IS.
HOWEVER, SECURITY CAN NEVER BE
HUNDRED PERCENT.
WE ARE TRYING GET TO A POINT WE
ARE PREVENTING ADVERSARY AND
DELAYING AN ADVERSARY FROM
GETTING TO A CERTAIN POINT.
FOR THE TIME, TO BE ASKING WHAT
THE SCHOOL IS DOING AND RIGHT
FOR THAT TYPE OF SCHOOL.
NOW, WE SEE DYNAMICS HAVE
CHGED AND THIS THE TYPE OF
INCIDENT WE NEED TO BE LOOKING
AT IT DIFFERENTLY.
>> Heather: YOU JUST REFERENCED
THAT PARENTS ALL ACROSS THE
COUNTRY WATCHING THIS UNFOLD,
THEY HAVE TO SEND THEIR LITTLE
CHILDREN TO SCHOOL ON MONDAY.
"A", HOW DO THEY DO THAT AND "B"
WHAT DO THEY ASK 'YOUR SCHOOLS
ABOUT SECURITY?
>> IT MUST BE VERY DIFFICULT.
ANY SMALL CHILD OFF TO SCHOOL
AFTER WHAT WE SAW WHAT HAPPENED
YESTERDAY.
ONE OF THE THINGS THAT PARENTS
CAN DO.
THEY WOULD LIKE TO DO SOMETHING
POSITIVE TO PROTECT THEIR FAMILY
AND LOVED ONES.
ASK THE QUESTION TO THE SCHOOL,
WHAT ARE THEY DOING.
WHAT ARE THE PROCEDURES?
COULD IT BE BETTER?
THE ACTIVITY BY INDIVIDUALS,
THAT IS WHAT THIS COUNTRY IS
GREAT ABOUT, INDIVIDUALS
STEPPING UP, INDIVIDUALS ASKING
A QUESTION, INDIVIDUALS TAKING
RESPONSIBILITY.
I THINK IT IS WHAT WE HAVE TO BE
DOING THAT.
TYPE OF DIALOGUE, IF YOU ARE A
PARENT THE ABILITY TO UNDERSTAND
WHAT THEY ARE DOING TO PROTECT
YOUR CHILDREN, BUT MAYBE SUGGEST
WAYS THEY COULD ENHANCE IT.
I THINK THAT IS WHAT PEOPLE CAN
DO AND MAKE THEM FEEL BETTER
ABOUT SENDING CHILDREN OFF ON
MONDAY.
>> AS WE SPEAK TO YOU, WE ARE
LOOKING AT HORRIBLE PICTURES.
LAW ENFORCEMENT DID ARRIVE FIRST
ON THE SCENE.
PARENTS, FRIENDS REACTS GO.
WHAT IS YOUR TAKE ON THE TRAGEDY
IN WHAT HAPPENED IN HOW YOU
THINK LAW ENFORCEMENT RESPONDED?
>> WELL, I THOUGHT AND I WAS
LISTENING TO IT AND ACTUALLY
COMMENTING ON IT ON YOUR CHANNEL
YESTERDAY AS IT WAS UNFOLDING.
I CAN TELL YOU WHAT I WAS
HEARING LAW ENFORCEMENT DID ALL
WHAT WE EXPECT THEM TO DO.
LOCAL POLICE ARRIVED AS QUICKLY
AS POSSIBLE.
CERTAINLY THE TAPES ARE VERY
ENCOURAGING, THEY WERE THERE
VERY QUICKLY.
MULTIPLE AGENCIES WERE IN PLACE
SEARCHING THE AREA AROUND THE
FACILITY LOOKING FOR LEADS.
WITHIN A COUPLE OF HOURS, THEY
WERE GOING ACROSS STATE LINES.
THEY HAD THIS CONNECTION WHICH
WAS STILL UNSURE WITH HOBOKEN,
NEW JERSEY WHICH TURNS OUT TO BE
THES BROTHER.
SO VERY QUICKLY THE LAW
ENFORCEMENT RESPONDED WELL.
WE WOULD LIKE TO HAVE RESPONDED
BEFORE HE GOT THERE BUT
SOMETIMES THAT DOESN'T HAPPEN.
>> Heather: THE SHOOTING TOOK
THREE MINUTES AND AFFECTED SO
MANY LIVES.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
WE APPRECIATE YOUR INSIGHT, BILL
DALY.
>> YOU ARE WELCOME.
>> Gregg: MOMENTS AGO,
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
RELEASING THE NAMES OF THE 26
PEOPLE KILLED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
ALL SIX ADULTS WERE WOMEN.
OF THE 20 CHILDREN SHOT, EIGHT
WERE BOYS, 12 WERE GIRLS AND ALL
OF THE CHILDREN AGES SIX OR
SEVEN.
>> Heather: WE CONTINUE TO
SEARCH FOR ANSWERS AS THE NATION
MOURNS THIS TRAGEDY WITH THE
PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
ONE PSYCHIATRIST PREVENTING
THESE CRIMES IS LIKE TRYING TO
FIND A NEEDLE IN A VERY LARGE
HAYSTACK.
[ Male Announcer ]
RED LOBSTER'S CRABFEST
ENDS SOON.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OURENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
TILL YOU FINISH YOUR VEGETABLES.
[ clock ticking ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THERE'S A BETTER WAY...
V8 V-FUSION.
VEGETABLE NUTRITION THEY NEED,
FRUIT TASTE THEY LOVE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
OR...TRY KIDS BOXES!
COULD'V♪ HAD A V8.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
>>> I'VE BEEN AT THIS FOR A
THIRD OF A CENTURY, IT'S MY
SENSIBILITIES MAY NOT BE THE
AVERAGE MAN -- BUT THIS PROBABLY
IS THE WORST I HAVE SEEN.
>> Gregg: CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICEMAN COMMENTING ON LEARNING
MORE ABOUT ADAM LANZA.
TRAGEDY LEAVING MANY FOLKS
WONDER IF ANYTHING COULD HAVE
BEEN DONE TO PREVENT IT.
SOME EXPERTS ARE NOW REFERRING
TO THE SHOOTING AS A BLACK SWAN
EVENT, AN EVENT SO RARE AND
DEVASTATING IT CANNOT BE
ANTICIPATED.
DR. ANDREW HARPER FROM THE
UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS, FINDING
SOMEBODY LIKE LANZA BEFORE THEY
ACT IS LIKE FINDING A NEEDLE IN
A HAYSTACK.
>> IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO PREDICT
WHO IS GOING TO BE THE ONE THAT
CARRIES THIS OUT.
>> Gregg: JOINING US WITH MORE,
HENRY CLOUD, AUTHOR OF
"NECESSARY ENDINGS."
THIS IS METAPHOR BUT THERE IS
GREAT REFERENCE ON THE INTERNET
AND JOURNALS OF ALL KINDS.
DO YOU BUY THIS?
>> WELL, I THINK YOU'VE GOT TO
MAKE A BIG DISTINCTION BETWEEN
PREVENTION AND PREDICTION.
HERE IS THE LOGIC OF IT ALL.
REALITY IS THAT PEOPLE THAT DO
THESE THINGS ARE MENTALLY ILL OR
THEY HAVE SOCIAL ISOLATION,
INABILITY TO CONNECT.
STRAINED CONNECTIONS.
SOME SORT OF DARK SIDE, BUT ONLY
A SMALL FRACTION OF MENTALLY ILL
PEOPLE OR SOCIALLY DISCONNECTED
PEOPLE END UP DOING SOMETHING
VIOLENT LIKE THIS.
SO THERE IS THE PROBLEM.
YOU CAN'T PREDICT WHO IS GOING
TO DO IT.
WHAT WE CAN DO, THIS IS WHAT WE
NEED TO FOCUS ON, WHAT WE CAN DO
WE CAN PREVENT THINGS FROM
GETTING TO THIS WHEN WE ALL HAVE
AN EYE ON PEOPLE THAT ARE
MENTALLY ILL AND THAT ARE
DISCONNECTED AND WE NEED TO
REACH OUT AND WE NEED TO MAKE
SLUR THEY DON'T FALL THROUGH THE
CRACKS.
>> Gregg: HE WAS DESCRIBED AS A
LONER, RATHER STRANGE, HAD
DIFFICULTY IN SOCIAL SITUATIONS.
HE WAS DEVOID OF FRIENDS.
GIVEN THOSE CIRCUMSTANCES, DO
YOU SEE A CONNECTION HERE?
>> YOU ALWAYS SEE A CONNECTION
THERE.
IT GETS MORE CONFUSING BECAUSE
YOU ALSO HEAR OTHER REPORTS OF
PEOPLE THAT DESCRIBE HIM AS A
MEMBER OF THE CLASS, THE
COMMUNITY AND YOU SEE BOTH.
IN MANY TIMES BECAUSE PEOPLE ARE
INTEGRATED ON THE OUTSIDE INTO
COMMUNITIES AND CLUBS AND
CIRCLES OF FRIENDS, THE
ASSUMPTION IS MADE THAT THEY ARE
MORE INTEGRATED AND CONNECTED ON
THE INSIDE THAN THEY REALLY ARE.
WHAT HAPPENS IS A LOT OF TIMES
THEY HAVE A SECRET, DARK IN PAIN
AND CONFUSED OR MENTALLY ILL
SIDE OF THEM THAT NOBODY
CONSISTENTLY GETTING CLOSE TO TO
BE ABLE TO RECOGNIZE.
THAT IS WHY, FOR EXAMPLE, AS A
MENTAL HEALTH PROFESSIONAL, WHEN
WE'RE UP CLOSE AND PERSONAL WITH
A LOT OF PEOPLE WHO ARE GOING
THROUGH THINGS, THEY MAKE
SPECIFIC STATEMENTS OR THREATS.
WE KNOW ENOUGH WE CAN MAKE THE
CALL AND HAVE THEM ARRESTED.
MANY TIMES PEOPLE DON'T HAVE
ANYBODY THAT CLOSE THAT IS
HEARING THIS STUFF.
>> Gregg: THEY EXAMINED 37
DEADLY INCIDENTS INVOLVING 41
PERPETRATORS, ONLY 17% HAD A
PRIOR MENTAL ILLNESS DIAGNOSIS.
SO THERE DOESN'T SEEM TO BE A
STRONG CORRELATION THERE.
HAVING SAID THAT THE BROTHER OF
THE KILLER SAID THAT HIS BROTHER
WAS AUTISTIC AND MADE HAVE HAD
ASPERGER'S.
THERE IS A BIG GAP BETWEEN A
PRIOR DIAGNOSIS AND PEOPLE THAT
ARE STRUGGLING AND
UNDIAGNOSISED, AS WELL.
THE BIG POINTED WHEN THERE ARE
FRIENDS AND FAMILY AND COMMUNITY
MEMBERS THAT YOU KNOW, IT'S JUST
NOT OKAY THAT THEY ARE
DISCONNECTED IN SOME WAY OR
WITHDRAWN OR HURT.
WE ALWAYS HAVE TO PULL THEM IN
AND DO AS MUCH AS WE CAN.
>> Gregg: PARENTS ARE SOMETIMES
IN DENIAL ABOUT THINGS LIKE
THAT?
>> YEAH, I'M A PARENT.
I'VE GOT TWO GIRLS.
THE NORMAL TEEN OR PRE-TEEN
SCENARIO IS YOU ARE ALWAYS
TRYING TO BRIDGE CONNECTIONS
BECAUSE THEY ARE TRYING TO HAVE
THE PARTS THEY KEEP AWAY FROM
PARENTS.
IT'S WHY WE HAVE STATISTICS,
EVEN ONE OR TWO FAMILY DINNERS A
WEEK WE KNOW IS CORE RELATED
WITH A LOT OF BAD STUFF SO
PARENTS KNOW WAS THE KIDS ARE
THINKING.
NOWHERE THEIR HURTS ARE AND
WHERE THEY FEEL SLEIGHTED BY
OTHER KIDS.
WE HAVE TO STAY CLOSE TO THEIR
LITTLE HEART, WE FORGET AND
STILL BE CONFUSED OR WOUNDED.
>> Gregg: IT SEEMS LIKE IT IS
HAPPENING SO MUCH.
EVEN THE PRESIDENT POINTED THAT
OUT, AND YET THERE IS A STUDY
OUT THAT POINTS OUT IT'S
ACTUALLY ON THE DECLINE, THESE
MASS MURDER INCIDENTS IN
SHOPPING MALLS AND SCHOOLS.
THE BOTTOM LINE THERE ARE TENS
OF THOUSANDS OF SCHOOLS IN
AMERICA.
VAST MAJORITY OF THEM ARE QUITE
SAFE?
>> YEAH, I READ ONE REPORT ON
THE INTERNET ABOUT HOW PEOPLE
ARE EXPLAINING IT TO PARENTS.
IT'S SO RARE.
IF YOU GET THE REAL STATISTIC OF
HOW MANY CHILDREN TO GO SCHOOL
AND ARE SAFE, BUT THE PROBLEM IS
WHEN WE DO HAVE SOMETHING AWFUL
HAPPEN EVEN TO ONE CHILD THEN
THAT TAKES THE HEARTS OF EVERY
PARENT AND EVERY HUMAN INTO HIGH
ALERT.
IT'S NORMAL AND NATURAL FOR US
TO GET MORE CONCERNED ABOUT
SECURITY.
THERE ARE MENTALLY ILL PEOPLE
BUT THERE ARE CRIMINAL MINDS.
WE HAVE HOSPITALS FOR THE
CRIMINALLY INSANE.
IT CALLS FOR A LOT OF VIGILANCE
FOR ALL OF US.
>> Gregg: DR. CLOUD, THANK YOU.
>> Heather: COMING UP A MOURNING
NATION LOOKING FOR ANSWERS, ANY
ANSWERS AFTER THE TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT.
HOW WILL THE FAMILIES OF NEWTOWN
FIND PEACE.
UP NEXT, THE ROLE THAT FAITH CAN
PLAY.
FATHER JONATHAN MOORE IT'S IS
HERE.
EVEN BABIES.
CHEVRON IS WORKING TO STOP
MOTHER-TO-CHILD TRANSMISSION.
OUR EMPLOYEES AND THEIR FAMILIES
ARE PART OF THE FIGHT.
AND WE'RE WINNING.
AT CHEVRON NIGERIA, WE HAVEN'T
HAD A REPORTED CASE IN 12EARS.
AIDS IS STRONG.
BUT WE ARE STRONGER.
AND AIDS...
♪
AIDS IS GOING TO LOSE.
Neural speeds
increasing to 4G LTE.
Brain upgrading to a quad-core
processor.
Predictive intelligence
with Google Now complete.
Introducing DROID DNA by HTC.
It's not an upgrade
to your phone.
It's an upgrade to yourself.
>>.
>> Gregg: MORE NOW ON OUR TOP
STORY.
THE NATION COMING TO GRIPS ON
THE INCIDENT.
28 PEOPLE ARE DEAD INCLUDING THE
SUSPECTED GUNMAN'S MOTHER.
20 OF THEM WERE CHILDREN THAT
WERE KILLED.
ACCORDING TO THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER MANY OF THEM WERE SHOT
CLOSE RANGE MULTIPLE TIMES.
ALL BEFORE THE SHOOTING SUSPECT
IDENTIFIED AS 20-YEAR-OLD TURNED
THE GUN ON HIMSELF.
THE NEWS SENDING SHOCK WAVES IN
THE CLOSE-KNIT TOWN.
HERE IS HOW THE TERRIBLE EVENTS
UNFOLDING.
>> EVIL VISITED IN COMMUNITY
TODAY.
>> A CALL CAME INTO DISPACH.
RESOURCES FROM ALL THE STATE
RACED TO THAT AREA AS THEY
CONVERGED ON THE SCHOOL.
[ SIREN ]
>> CHILDREN OBVIOUSLY WERE VERY
SHAKEN AND CRYING.
THE POLICE MADE THEM HOLD HANDS
AND TOLD THEM TO CLOSE THEIR
EYES.
>> THEY HAVE ENTIRE LIVES AHEAD
OF THEM, BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS.
>> MY GYM TEACHER SAID STAY
AGAINST THE WALL AND EVERYBODY
KIND OF PANICKING.
>> THERE IS NO WORD, HERE IS
TERROR.
>> DOESN'T EVEN SEEM REAL.
IT DOES NOT SEEM LIKE IT IS EVEN
POSSIBLE.
>> WE ALL HUDDLED AND I KEPT
HEARING THESE BOOMING NOISES.
>> TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHAT IS
GOING ON.
>> THE KIDS WERE TERRIFIED.
THEY WERE TERRIFIED.
THEY HAD JUST WITNESSED
SOMETHING.
THEY WERE TERRIFIED.
>> MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF
THE VICTIMS AND IN THE WORDS,
HEAL THE BROKENHEARTED AND BIND
UP THEIR WOUNDS.
>> Gregg: KNEW, AS WE TRY TO
MAKE SENSE OF THIS TERRIBLE, WE
GO TO MIKE TOBIN WITH THE VERY
LATEST.
>> Reporter: YOU MENTIONED HOW
THIS IS TOWN SMALL ENOUGH THAT
EVERYONE KNOWS SOMEONE WHO HAS
BEEN TOUCHED BY THIS TRAGEDY.
THEY ARE COMINGETHER TO
GRIEVE.
FOCAL POINT FOR THE GRIEVING HAS
BECOME ST. ROSE OF LIMA CATHOLIC
CHURCH.
WE SAW PEOPLE GETTING THEIR ARMS
AROUND EACH OTHER AS THEY ARE
TRYING TO GET THEIR ARMS AROUND
WHAT HAPPENED.
BRACING EACH OTHER AS THEY TRY
TO GET THROUGH THIS TRAGEDY.
>> I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO DO BECAUSE
WE'VE NEVER BEEN FACED WITH
SOMETHING OF THIS MAGNITUDE.
OUR FOCUS IS THE KIDS.
WE HAVE ENOUGH TIME DEALING WITH
IT AS ADULTS, PROCESSING ALL THE
INFORMATION BUT THE FOCUS IS THE
KIDS AND TRYING TO GET THEM
THROUGH THIS.
>> Reporter: FOR OBVIOUS REASONS
THE SCHOOLS ALL WENT TO LOCKDOWN
AS INFORMATION CAME OUT AND
SLOWLY AND SURELY THE KIDS BEGIN
TO LEARN THIS WAS NOT A DRILL.
>> ALL THE KIDS WHO HAD SIBLINGS
THERE WERE SO WORRIED AND DIDN'T
KNOW WHAT TO DO.
>> Reporter: THOSE REMARKABLY
LITTLE GIRLS ATTEMPTED TO
CONSOLE THEIR CLASSMATES AND
MAKE THEM FEEL BETTER.
THEY JUST DIDN'T HAVE ENOUGH
INFORMATION.
THAT BEING SAID.
GRIEF COUNSELORS HAVE BEEN SENT
TO THIS TOWN.
VOLUNTEERS FROM ALL OF THE
NEIGHBORING STATES.
THERE ARE TWO DIFFERENT SECTIONS
OF THE GRIEF COUNSELING
OPERATION, ONE FOR ADULTS AND
ONE FOR CHILDREN.
CHILDREN SECTION THEY PUT EXTRA
EFFORT TO TRY TO TAKE THE EDGE
OFF THE KIDS.
THEY HAVE THERAPY DOGS THERE AND
ROOMS FILLED WITH STUFFED
ANIMALS.
ON A BRIGHT NOTE THOSE TOYS HAVE
BEEN SENT IN BY PEOPLE FROM ALL
OVER THE COUNTRY.
>> Gregg: MIKE, THANK YOU.
>> Heather: AS THE ENTIRE NATION
COMES TO GRIPS WITH THE SHOOTING
RAMPAGE IN CONNECTICUT.
NEWTOWN RESIDENTS ARE SEARCHING
FOR ANSWERS, REALLY THE WHOLE
COUNTRY IS WHILE TRYING TO COPE
WITH THE TRAGEDY AND LOSS OF 20
YOUNG CHILDREN.
YOU SO HOW WERE THESE RESIDENTS
BEGIN TO FIND PEACE AGAIN.
FATHER JONATHAN MORRIS IS A
CONTRIBUTOR AND JOINS US NOW.
HOW DO ANY OF US BEGIN TO MAKE
SENSE OF THIS TRAGEDY?
>> IF I WERE THERE, HEATHER, MY
ONLINE ANSWER WOULD BE A HUG.
MY ONLY ANSWER WOULD BE TO THOSE
THAT ARE SUFFERING MOST DEEPLY
BECAUSE THERE IS NO THEOLOGICAL
SOLUTION TO THIS EXCEPT HEAVEN.
EXCEPT ETERNAL LIFE BUT THAT IS
NOT WHAT THESE FAMILIES ARE
THINKING ABOUT RIGHT NOW.
A LITTLE BIT THOSE THAT WERE
WATCHING TRYING TO FIND ANSWERS.
LET ME TELL YOU HOW I DEAL WITH
THIS.
WHEN I LOOK AT SUCH TERRIBLE
ABUSES OF FREE WILL LIKE THIS.
THE FIRST THING I DO IS CRY.
THE SECOND THING I DO IS TO
STAND IN AWE OF HOW MUCH GOD
MUCH VALUE THE PROPERTIES OF
FREEDOM WHICH IS LOVE.
TO VALUE IT SO MUCH HE WOULD
RISK A VERY SMALL PART OF THE
POPULATION ABUSING IT IN WAY
THAT WOULD AFFECT THE LITTLE
CHILDREN, THE LEAST OF THESE THE
MOST LOVED SO GRAVELY AND
DEEPLY.
I THINK GOD IS WITH THE FAMILIES
RIGHT NOW.
HE WAS WITH THE CHILDREN WHEN
THEY SUFFERED AND DIED AND HE
WILL BE WITH ALL OF US AS WE
DECIDE TO DOUBLE DOWN ON LOVE
WHICH IS THE ONLY SOLUTION UNTIL
WE GET TO THE HEAVEN.
>> Heather: IS THAT THE ANSWER
TO THE QUESTION, IF YOU BELIEVE
IN GOD, WHY WOULD GOD ALLOW THIS
TO HAPPEN BECAUSE HE DID THIS
FREE WILL?
>> ITS GREAT QUESTION.
ITS REAL QUESTION, I WISH I
COULD SAY THERE WAS A PERFECT
ANSWER.
BUT I DO BELIEVE FROM THE BIBLE
AND FROM MY OWN EXPERIENCE, THAT
GOD DOES MAKES US A PROMISE.
OUT OF EVERY SINGLE INSTANCE OF
SUFFERING AND EVIL IN THIS WORLD
HE WILL BRING OUT A GREATER GOOD
IF WE LET HIM.
IT'S NOT A PROMISE THAT IT WILL
BE IMMEDIATE BUT IT'S A PROMISE
THAT HE KNOWS US, HE LOVES US
AND HE CARES US.
IT'S ULTIMATE SOLUTION IS BEING
IN HEAVEN AND ETERNITY.
LOVING ONE ANOTHER AND HUGGING
ONE ANOTHER AND SAYING, WE'RE
GOING TO DOUBLE DOWN ON LOVE.
>> Heather: RIGHT HERE AT THIS
TIME OF YEAR, CHRISTMAS,
HANUKKAH AND LITTLE CHILDREN
EXCITED ABOUT PRESENTS AND GIFTS
THE TIME WHAT IS A TIME OF HOPE,
HOW DO THESE FAMILIES MOVE
FORWARD DURING THIS TIME IN
PARTICULAR?
WE HEARD FAMILIES AND RESIDENTS
TAKING DOWN THEIR CHRISTMAS
DECORATIONS BECAUSE THEY FEEL
GUILTY?
>> THAT IS UNDERSTANDABLE.
WE'RE NOT SPIRITUAL BEINGS BUT
WE'RE EMOTIONAL BEINGS AND WE'RE
SPIRITUAL BEINGS.
THOSE THREE ELEMENTS NEEDS TO BE
RESPECTED.
I WOULD NEVER GO IN HERE IS THE
THEOLOGICAL SOLUTION.
I WOULD BE THERE CLOSELY
PSYCHOLOGICALLY AND EMOTIONALLY
AND MAKE SURE THEIR PHYSICAL
NEEDS ARE MET.
NEIGHBORS BRINGING FOOD OVER TO
NEIGHBORS AND NEIGHBORS SENDING
CARDS AND GIFTS.
WE HEARD THAT FROM MIKE TOBIN
PEOPLE SENDING TED DPI BEARS.
THAT IS GOD'S WAY OF REACHING
OUT TO THOSE THAT SUFFER.
YOU AND ME BEING THE HANDS AND
FEET OF JESUS.
>> Heather: WHAT SHOULD OTHER
PEOPLE SAY TO THEIR CHILDREN?
>> I THINK SO MANY PEOPLE HAVE
TOLD ME TODAY THROUGH SOCIAL
MEDIA, WHAT DO I SAY TO MY KIDS.
MY SUGGESTION WOULD BE, JUST BE
VERY CLEAR AND CON CONCISE ABOUT
THE THINGS YOU KNOW.
YOU ARE NOT IN DANGER RIGHT NOW.
I WILL PROTECT YOU.
YOU CAN'T PROTECT PERFECTLY BUT
A PARENT CAN SAY TO HIS CHILD, I
WILL PROTECT YOU.
SECONDLY, YOU CAN SAY THAT YOUR
PLACE OF EDUCATION IS SAFE,
CLEAR SIMPLE ANSWERS.
THEN THIRDLY, AUTHOR THOSE THAT
DO HAVE FAITH, IT'S A TIME TO
TALK ABOUT THAT.
THAT THIS LIFE IS HARD SOMETIMES
BUT WE'RE ON JOURNEY TOWARD
ANOTHER LIFE WHERE EVERYTHING
WILL BE WIPED AWAY.
IN TIMES OF TRAGEDY, IT'S THE
CORE OF WHO WE ARE.
IT'S A GREAT TIME TO REFLECT
WHEN THINGS ARE GOING GOOD, THAT
IS ALSO REFLECT ON WHO WE ARE
AND CORE, WHICH IS MY OPINION,
THAT GOD MADE US AND LOVED US
AND HAS A GREAT PLAN FOR US IN
THE FUTURE.
>> Heather: AT THE SAME TIME WE
HAVE AN OVERWHELMING SENSE TODAY
IN PARTICULAR AND YESTERDAY OF
EVIL IN THIS WORLD.
SENSE OF HOPELESSNESS.
YOU CAN SAY TO YOUR CHILD, I'M
GOING PROTECT YOU.
YOU SEND THEM OFF TO SCHOOL AND
IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
WE HAVE INCIDENTS LIKE THIS
HAPPEN.
HOW DO WE DEAL WITH THAT?
>> THERE IS A DEEP AND GOOD
QUESTION.
AS KIDS GET OLDER WE HAVE TO
EXPLAIN, I CAN'T PROTECT YOU
PERFECTLY BECAUSE THERE IS EVIL.
I BELIEVE THAT TO BE A
SUPERNATURAL POWER.
WE LOOK AT THE ONE WHO INFLICTED
THIS GREAT CRIME, WE CAN SEE
SOMETHING BUT IT'S A COMBINATION
PROBABLY OF MENTAL ILLNESS,
PRESENT OF EVIL IN HIS LIFE AND
GIVING HIMSELF OVER TO EVIL.
THIRDLY THE ABUSE OF THAT
INCREDIBLE MYSTERIOUS GIFT OF
FREE WILL.
PERSONAL DECISION, WE CAN HELP
OUR CHILDREN TO RECOGNIZE THAT
THEY DO NOT HAVE TO GO DOWN THAT
PATH.
THEY CAN MAKE GOOD DECISIONS
WITH THE GREAT GIFT OF FREE WILL
THAT GOD HAS GIVEN TO THEM.
>> Heather: FATHER MORRIS,
HOPEFULLY THAT BROUGHT COMFORT
TO PEOPLE.
>> Gregg: PEOPLE ARE TRYING TO
COME TO GRIPS WHAT HAPPENED AT
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
WE'LL TEAK SFEEK A MOTHER WHOSE
DAUGHTER WAS INSIDE THAT SCHOOL
AND MANAGED TO ESCAPE THE
SHOOTING.
WHY DO TOYS FOR TOTS AND HASBRO
TRUST DURACELL TO POWER
THEIR DONATED TOYS?
DURALOCK POWER PRESERVE.
IT LOCKS IN POWER
FOR UP TO 10 YEARS IN STORAGE.
GUARANTEED.
DURACELL WITH DURALOCK.
TRUSTED EVERYWHERE.
IS EFFICIENTLY ABSORBED IN SMALL
CONTINUOUS AMOUNTS.
Citracal Slow Release
CONTINUOUSLY RELEASES CALCIUM
PLUS D
WITH EFFICIENT ABSORPTION
IN ONE DAILY DOSE.
Citracal Slow Release.
GIVES YOU 1% CASH BACK
ON ALL PURCHASES,
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS.
AND EVERYONE...BUT HER
LIKES 50% MORE CASH.
BUT I'M UPPING MY GAME.
DO YOU WANT A CANDY CANE?
YES!
DO YOU WANT THE PUPPY?
DO YOU WANT A TRICYCLE?
YES!
DO YOU WANT
50 PERCENT MORE CASH?
NO!
♪
FESTIVE.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE Capital One
Cash Rewards Card
GIVES YOU
1% CASH BACK
ON EVERY
PURCHASE
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS
ON THE CASH YOU EARN.
IT'S THE CARD FOR PEOPLE
WHO LIKE MORE CASH.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
I HAD[ Designer ]EELINGE
ENOUGH OF JUST COVERING UP
MY MODERATE TO SEVERE
PLAQUE PSORIASIS.
I DECIDED ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
♪
[ Spa Lady ]
I STARTED ENBREL.
IT'S CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO PROVIDE CLEARER SKIN.
[ RV Guy ] ENBREL MAY NOT WORK
FOR EVERYONE --
AND MAY NOT CLEAR YOU
COMPLETELY,
BUT FOR MANY, IT GETS SKIN
CLEARER FAST, WITHIN 2 MONTHS,
AND KEEPS IT CLEARER
UP TO 9 MONTHS.
[ Male Announcer ]
BECAUSE ENBREL®, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL,
EVENTS INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS, LYMPHOMA,
OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING ENBREL,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START ENBREL IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON ENBREL, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING,
OR PALENESS.
IF YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH, ASK
YOUR DERMATOLOGIST ABOUT ENBREL.
>>.
>> Gregg: QUICK CHECK.
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON IS RECOVERING FROM A
CONCUSSION.
SHE IS RUMORED BEEN FIGHTING A
STOMACH VIRUS AND FAINTED AFTER
BECOMING DEHYDRATED.
FOX NEWS HAS LEARNED THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA EXPECTED TO
FORMALLY NOMINATE JOHN KERRY AS
THE NEXT SECRETARY OF STATE.
SOURCES SAY, IT'S BASICALLY A
DONE DEAL.
SOURCES SAY KERRY WILL BE TAPPED
TO THE POST SHORTLY, POSSIBLY
WITHIN DAYS.
>> EGYPTIANS CASTING BALLOTS ON
A DRAFT CONSTITUTION AMID HEAVY
SECURITY.
ISLAMIST BACKED CHARTER IS
CAUSING A DEEP DIVIDE IN THAT
NATION.
>> Heather: YOU ARE LOOKING AT
SCENE AT OUR NATION'S CAPITOL,
WHERE FLAGS ARE FLYING
HALF-STAFF TODAY.
LAWMAKERS LEADING IN MOURNING
THE TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT.
MOLLY HAS MORE FROM WASHINGTON.
>> TODAY IN HIS WEEKLY RADIO AND
INTERNET ADDRESS, HE HONORED THE
TEACHERS AND ADMINISTRATORS AND
STUDENTS WHO WERE KILLED IN THE
CONNECTICUT SHOOL SHOOTING.
SHE DESCRIBED THE MURDERED
STUDENTS AS YOUNG CHILDREN WITH
WHOLE LIVES AHEAD OF THEM.
>> OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN TODAY.
WE GRIEVE FOR THE FAMILIES OF
THOSE WE LOST.
WE KEEP IN OUR PRAYERS THE
PARENTS OF THOSE WHO SURVIVED
BECAUSE AS BLESSED AS THEY TO
HAVE THEIR CHILDREN HOME THEY
KNOW THEIR CHILD'S INNOCENCE HAS
BEEN TORN BY THE WAY.
>> Molly: FLAGS WERE LOWERED TO
HALF-STAFF IN HONOR TO THOSE
THAT WERE KILLED.
USUALLY THE REPUBLICANS WOULD
PUT OUT A RADIO AND SBRCHBT
ADDRESS BUT JOHN BOEHNER PUT OUT
A STATEMENT INSTEAD AFTER THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING, SAYING, QUOTE,
THERE WILL BE NO WEEKLY
REPUBLICAN ADDRESS THIS WEEKEND
SO THAT PRESIDENT OBAMA CAN
SPEAK FOR THE ENTIRE NATION AT
THIS TIME OF MOURNING.
I JOIN THE PRESIDENT AND ALL
AMERICANS IN SENDING PRAYERS AND
CONDOLENCES TO THE VICTIMS LOVED
ONES.
JANET NAPOLITANO SAYS THAT
DEPARTMENT WILL PROVIDE, QUOTE,
ANY SUPPORT NECESSARY TO STATE
AND LOCAL OFFICIALS ON THE SCENE
IN NEWTOWN.
>> Heather: MOLLY HENNEBERG LIVE
FROM WASHINGTON.
>> Gregg: COMING UP INFORM
NEW YORK CITY MAYOR THAT HELP
LEAD THE COUNTRY THROUGH 9/11
ATTACKS RESPONDS TO THE
CONNECTICUT SHOOTING.
AN INTERVIEW WITH AMERICA'S
MAYOR RUDY GULIANI IS STRAIGHT
AHEAD.
[ Male Announcer ]
RED LOBSTER'S
HITTING THE STREETS
TO TELL REAL PEOPLE ABOUT
OUR NEW 15 UNDER $15 MENU.
OH MY GOODNESS!
OH MY GOSH,
THIS LOOKS AMAZING!
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR NEW MAINE STAYS!
15ENTREES UNDER $15,
SEAFOOD, CHICKEN AND MORE!
OOTHE TILAPIAWITH ROASTEDEGETAB!
I'M ACTUALLY LOOKING AT
THE WO GRILLED CHICKEN
WITH PORTOBELLO WINE SAUCE.
AT PORK CHOP
WAS GREAT!
NO MORE
FAST FOOD FRIDAY'S!
WE'RE GOING TO GO
TO RED LOBSTER.
YEP.
[ Male Announcer ]
COME TRY OUR NEW MENU
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
SALAD, SANDWICHES, AND MORE.
I'M GOING TO DREAM
ABOUT THAT STEAK.
ABOUT THAT TIRAMISU.
WHAT A NIGHT, HUH?
BUT, UM, CAN THE TEST DRIVE
BE OVER NOW?
HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A PASSAT.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN, $0 DUE AT SIGNING,
$0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
>>.
>> Gregg: WELCOME BACK.
EARLIER TODAY, FORMER NEW YORK
MAYOR RUDY GULIANI THAT LED THE
CITY DURING THE 9/11 TERROR
ATTACKS SPOKE TO JON SCOTT.
>> IT'S VERY HARD NOT TO FEEL
THE EMOTION LIKE THIS.
ALL THE PARENTS OR EVEN ONES
THAT AREN'T PARENTS.
NECESSITY UNDERSTAND CHILDREN
AND THEY UNDERSTAND TO HAVE
THESE INNOCENT CHILLED MOWED
DOWN AND THE INCOMPREHENSIBLE
ACT.
HOW DOES SOMEONE STAND IN FRONT
OF A CLASSROOM AND KALE FIVE OR
SIX-YEAR-OLD.
IT COMPLETELY IS IMPOSSIBLE FOR
ANY VAGUELY NORMAL PERSON TO
UNDERSTAND THAT.
>> THIS SCHOOL APPARENTLY HAD
DONE EVERYTHING RIGHT.
YOU CANNOT, EVEN IF THEY TURNED
THE STOOL INTO A FORTRESS.
>> IN A COMMUNITY LIKE THAT,
THEY DID MORE IN A COMMUNITY
LIKE THAT I WOULD THINK YOU
WOULD GENERALLY DO.
IN A COMMUNITY ONE VIOLENT
CRIME.
THIS ISN'T A DANGEROUS SUBURBAN
OR URBAN AREA.
THEY HAD MORE SECURITY THAN ANY
FACTS WOULD SUGGEST.
THE GUY BASICALLY, SHOT HIS WAY
IN.
SHOULD THEY HAVE ARMED POLICE
OFFICER THERE?
NOTHING IN THE PAST WOULD
SUGGEST THAT.
HAVING AN ARMED POLICE OFFICER
IS DISCONCERTING FOR THE
CHILDREN.
WHO WOULDN'T SAY HE WOULD HAVE
SHOT THE ARMED POLICE OFFICER.
THIS KID, TWO THINGS ABOUT HIM.
LOOKS LIKE HE KNEW HOW TO SHOT
SHOOT.
VERY GOOD SHOOTING IN A VERY
SHORT PERIOD OF TIME.
IT LOOKS LIKE HE DISTURBED BUT
SMART KID.
>> THAT IS WHAT EVERYBODY SAYS.
>> THAT IS DANGEROUS KILLER.
>> Gregg: RUDY GULIANI.
WE ARE GOING HEARING MOMENTARILY
FROM THE GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT
DAN MALLOY SET TO SPEAK TO THE
PEOPLE OF HIS STATE VIA
TELEVISION TH FROM HIS OFFICE.
WE'LL BRING THAT TO YOU LIVE AS
SOON AS IT BEGINS.
>> Heather: STUNNING NEW
DEVELOPMENTS IN THE
INVESTIGATION INTO ONE OF THE
DEADLIEST SHOOTINGS IN U.S.
HISTORY AS POLICE RELEASE THE
NAMES OF THE VICTIMS TO THE
PUBLIC AND THEY DESCRIBE THEIR
INJURIES IN MORE DETAIL.
HELLO, EVERYONE.
I'M HEATHER CHILDERS.
WELCOME TO A BRAND-NEW HOUR, A
HARD DAY INSIDE AMERICA'S NEWS
HEADQUARTERS.
>> Gregg: AND I'M GREGG JARRETT.
WE'RE GLAD YOU'RE WITH US.
THE NATION MOURNING THE LOSS OF
SO MANY YOUNG LIVES, 20 OF THE
26 PEOPLE MASSACRED AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, SOME AS
YOUNG AS SIX.
IN A NEWS CONFERENCE WRAPPING A
SHORT WHILE AGO, THE CHIEF STATE
MEDICAL EXAMINER SAYING THAT
MANY OF THE VICTIMS WERE KILLED
BY MULTIPLE CLOSE RANGE GUN
SHOTS.
>> Heather: SHEAR A NEW PICTURE
OF THE SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA.
POLICE SAYING THE 20-YEAR-OLD
FORCED HIS WAY INTO THE SCHOOL
AND CONTRARY TO EARLIER REPORTS,
LANZA DID HAVE AN ASSAULT RIFLE
ON HIM AS HE CARRIED OUT THE
MURDEROUS RAMPAGE.
>> Gregg: ALL OF THIS AS THE
TINY AND CLOSE-KNIT COMMUNITY OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT IS JUST
REELING FROM THIS TRAGEDY.
EARLIER TODAY, THE STATE CHIEF
MEDICAL EXAMINER DESCRIBED WHAT
HE CALLED THE WORST INCIDENT HE
HAS EVER SEEN.
>> I'VE BEEN AT THIS FOR A THIRD
OF A CENTURY AND IT'S -- MY
SENSIBILITIES MAY NOT BE THE
AVERAGE MAN.
BUT THIS PROBABLY IS THE WORST I
HAVE SEEN.
>> Gregg: MOLLY LINE IS LIVE
FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT WITH
THE LATEST.
HI, MOLLY.
>> HI, GREGG.
WE'VE GOTTEN A CHANCE TO LOOK
OVER THE NAMES ON THE LIST OF
THE VICTIMS  THAT WERE KILLED IN
THIS COMMUNITY.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT THE LIST, IT'S
LARGELY CHILDREN, 20 CHILDREN,
WITH NAMES YOU SEE IN CLASSROOMS
ALL ACROSS AMERICA.
CHARLOTTE, DANIEL, OLIVIA,
JESSE, THE YOUNGEST, A
SIX-YEAR-OLD BOY NAMED NOAH.
THE ADULTS, THE SIX ADULTS WERE
ALL WOMEN.
THE YOUNGEST WAS 27.
THE OLDEST, 56 YEARS OLD.
SO THIS GUNMAN WENT INTO THE
SCHOOL EARLY IN THE MORNING AND
KILLED WOMEN AND CHILDREN.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER, THE CHIEF
MEDICAL EXAMINER, HAVING A THIRD
OF A CENTURY OF EXPERIENCE
SAYING IT'S THE WORST HE OR HIS
COLLEAGUES HAVE SEEN.
THEY WORKED WELL INTO THE NIGHT
TO TRY TO BRING FAMILIES CLOSURE
AND IDENTIFY THE VICTIMS, TO
COMPLETE THEIR VERY DIFFICULT
TASK AND ABLE TO REUNITE THE
LOVED ONES WITH THEIR FAMILIES
THAT IN THE COMING DAYS WILL BE
PLANNING FUNERALS AND MEMORIAL
SERVICES AS THIS INVESTIGATION
CONTINUES.
THE SCHOOL IS STILL AN ACTIVE
INVESTIGATION.
>> Gregg: WE WANT TO GO LIVE TO
THE GOVERNOR, DAN MALLOY OF
CONNECTICUT.
LET'S LISTEN.
>> INDEED THE PEOPLE OF THE
WORLD WEEP FOR THE IMMEASURABLE
LOSSES SUFFERED BY THE FAMILIES
AND LOVED ONES OF THESE VICTIMS.
THOUGH WE COULD ALL TRY WHEN
SOMETHING AS SENSELESS AS THIS
OCCURS, THERE IS PRECIOUS LITTLE
ANYONE CAN SAY TO THE FAMILIES
THAT WILL LESSEN THE HORROR AND
SENSE OF LOSS THEY FEEL.
WE COULD SAY WE FEEL THEIR PAIN,
BUT THE TRUTH IS, WE CAN'T.
WHEN TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS TAKE
PLACE, PEOPLE OFTEN LOOK FOR
ANSWERS, AN EXPLANATION OF HOW
THIS COULD HAVE HAPPENED.
THE SAD TRUTH IS, THERE ARE NO
ANSWERS.
NO GOOD ONES, ANYWAY.
WE HAVE ALL SEEN TRAGEDIES LIKE
THIS PLAY OUT IN OTHER STATES
AND IN OTHER COUNTRIES.
EACH TIME WE HAVE WONDERED HOW
SOMETHING SO HORRIFIC COULD
OCCUR AND WE HAVE THANKED GOD
THAT IT DIDN'T HAPPEN HERE IN
OUR CONNECTICUT.
BUT NOW SADLY IT HAS.
SO WHAT CAN WE DO?
AS WAS NO DOUBT THE CASE LAST
NIGHT, WE CAN HUG SOMEONE WE
LOVE A LITTLE TIGHTER, AS HAS
BEEN HAPPENING SINCE YESTERDAY,
WE CAN SHOW AND SHARE WITH EACH
OTHER THE GRIEF WE FEEL FOR THE
CHILDREN AND ADULTS WHO WERE
KILLED AND FOR THEIR FAMILIES
AND LOVED ONES.
WE CAN SPEAK ABOUT WHAT'S REALLY
IMPORTANT AND WHAT CAN WAIT FOR
ANOTHER DAY.
THERE WILL BE TIME SOON FOR A
DISCUSSION OF PUBLIC POLICY
ISSUES SURROUNDING YESTERDAY'S
EVENTS.
BUT WHAT'S IMPORTANT RIGHT NOW
IS LOVE, COURAGE, AND
COMPASSION.
LOVE AS IT HAS POURED IN FROM
AROUND THE WORLD.
COURAGE AS IT WAS DEMONSTRATED
BY THE TEACHERS AND OTHER ADULTS
IN THE SCHOOL BUILDING WHOSE
ACTIONS NO DOUBT SAVED LIVES.
COURAGE ON DISPLAY AS IT ALWAYS
IS BY OUR FIRST RESPONDERS.
COMPASSION AS SHOWN BY PEOPLE
FROM AROUND CONNECTICUT WHO HAVE
ARRIVED IN NEWTOWN WANTING ONLY
TO HELP.
TOO OFTEN WE FOCUS ON WHAT
DIVIDES US AS A PEOPLE INSTEAD
OF WHAT BINDS US AS HUMAN
BEINGS.
WHAT WE SAW YESTERDAY WERE THOSE
BONDS, THAT SENSE OF COMMUNITY.
IN THE COMING DAYS, WE WILL RELY
ON THAT WHICH WE HAVE BEEN
TAUGHT AND THAT WHICH WE
INHERENTLY BELIEVE, THAT WE HAVE
FAITH FOR A REASON AND THAT
FAITH IS GOD'S GIFT TO US ALL.
THOSE EDUCATORS AND THOSE
INNOCENT LITTLE BOYS AND GIRLS
WERE TAKEN FROM THEIR FAMILIES
FAR TOO SOON.
LET US ALL HOPE AND PRAY THOSE
CHILDREN ARE NOW IN A PLACE
WHERE THAT INNOCENCE WILL
FOREVER BE PROTECTED.
MAY GOD BLESS YOU AND MAY GOD
BLESS THOSE 27 PEOPLE.
MAY GOD BLESS THEIR FAMILIES AND
FRIENDS AND MAY THE PAIN THEIR
LOVED ONES FEEL BE SOME DAY
ABSORBED BY THE LOVE OF ALL MAN
KIND.
>> Gregg: THE GOVERNOR OF THE
STATE OF CONNECTICUT, DAN
MALLOY, INNOCENT LITTLE BOYS AND
GIRLS TAKEN FROM THEIR FAMILIES
FAR TOO SOON.
HE SAID THERE ARE NO ANSWERS, NO
GOOD ONES, ANYWAY.
BACK TO MOLLY LINE STANDING BY
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
MOLLY, I APOLOGIZE FOR THE
INTERRUPTION.
WE DID WANT TO HEAR FROM THE
GOVERNOR, BUT PROVIDE US WITH AM
SO OF THE ADDITIONAL DETAILS
YOU'VE BEEN ABLE TO GLEAN AT THE
SCENE.
>> THE UNFORTUNATE THING SPEAK
MORE TO THE TRAGEDY AND HOW
HORRIFIC IT MUST HAVE BEEN FOR
THESE CHILDREN AND FOR THESE
WOMEN THAT WERE GUNNED DOWN IN
WHAT REALLY AMOUNTS TO A
MASSACRE.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER SAYING THEY
SUFFERED MULTIPLE GUNSHOT
WOUNDS, THAT THIS WAS A RIFLE
THAT WAS USED AND IN HIS WORDS,
THE WOUNDS WERE ALL OVER.
IN OTHER WORDS, THERE WAS NO
PARTICULAR AREA OF ANY
PARTICULAR VICTIM'S BODY THAT
THE SHOOTER APPEARED TO BE
AIMING FOR.
THAT MANY OF THE PEOPLE THAT
WERE GUNNED DOWN HAD MULTIPLE
GUNSHOT WOUNDS.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER SAYING HE
DID SEVEN OF THE ASSESSMENTS
HIMSELF AND THAT EACH OF THE
VICTIMS THAT HE ANDED HAD
BETWEEN THREE AND 11 GUNSHOT
WOUNDS WITH AT LEAST TWO
SUFFERING CLOSE RANGE GUN SHOTS.
WHEN HE WAS ASKED ABOUT HOW
PRECISE THIS GUNMAN WAS, HE SAID
HE COULDN'T REALLY SPEAK TO THAT
'CAUSE THAT WAS A DIFFICULT
THING TO SPEAK TO.
HE ALSO WANTED TO MAKE IT CLEAR
THAT HIS JOB, ESSENTIALLY THE
PAPERWORK WAS COMPLETED AND
THESE LOVED ONES, THESE
CHILDREN, THESE WIVES, THESE
MOTHERS WOULD BE ABLE TO BE
BROUGHT BACK TOGETHER WITH THEIR
FAMILIES SO THE PLANNING COULD
BEGIN FOR FUNERALS AND MEMORIAL
SERVICES AND THE COMMUNITY COULD
BEGIN TO COME TO GRIPS WITH THE
GRIEF THEY'LL BE SUFFERING.
SO MANY OF THE PEOPLE WE'VE
SPOKEN TO SINCE ARRIVING IN THIS
SMALL COMMUNITY HAVE BEEN
WAITING TO HEAR THE NAMES OF ALL
OF THESE VICTIMS TO FIND OUT IF
THIS WAS SOMEONE THEY KNEW OR IF
IT WAS A CHILD OF SOMEONE THAT
THEY WERE CLOSE TO.
NOW THOSE NAMES ARE COMING OUT
TONIGHT AND MANY OF THE PEOPLE
HERE WILL BE FINDING OUT IF IT'S
SOMEONE THEY KNOW OR IF IT'S
SOMEONE THAT MEANS A LOT TO THE
PEOPLE CLOSE TO THEM.
BUT THE COMMUNITY HAS ALL COME
TOGETHER AND AT THIS POINT, THEY
HAVE FELT AND FEARED THAT THEY
WOULD KNOW SOMEONE AND THEY ALL
HAVE BEEN BROUGHT MUCH CLOSER
TOGETHER.
GREGG?
>> Gregg: I JUST WANT TO CLEAR
UP, DID THE NEWS CONFERENCE
CLARIFY THE USE, IN ADDITION TO
TWO SEMIAUTOMATIC HAND GUNS, THE
USE OF AN ASSAULT RIFLE?
>> THERE WERE QUESTIONS ASKED
ABOUT THE WEAPONS BECAUSE THAT'S
BEEN A DEVELOPING PART OF ALL OF
THIS INVESTIGATION AND
THROUGHOUT THE DAY AND LAST MORE
THAN 24 HOURS, WE'VE GOTTEN
MULTIPLE DIFFERENT STORIES FROM
DIFFERENT LAW ENFORCEMENT
SOURCES.
SOME FEDERAL AND SOME LOCAL HERE
ON THE GROUND.
WE'RE TRYING TO CLARIFY THAT AT
THE PRESS CONFERENCE THIS
AFTERNOON.
THAT DIDN'T REALLY HAPPEN.
WE STILL HAVE WORD THAT THERE
WERE GUNS FOUND INSIDE THE
SCHOOL, BUT THE CLARIFICATION
ACTUALLY BECAME LESS CLEAR
REALLY.
HE SAID -- LIEUTENANT VANCE
SPEAKING THIS AFTERNOON,
RELEASING MUCH OF THE
INFORMATION, SAID THAT MAYBE
TOMORROW MORNING THEY'D BE ABLE
TO CLARIFY HOW MANY OF THE GUNS
WERE THERE, HOW MANY HAVE BEEN
FIRED, POSSIBLY THE NUMBER OF
ROUNDS, THAT SORT OF THING WOULD
BECOME MORE CLEAR.
RIGHT NOW THEY'RE STILL WORKING
THROUGH THAT.
>> Gregg: ALL RIGHT.
MOLLY LINE LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THANK YOU.
>> Heather: THERE IS NO WAY TO
COMPARE ONE HEARTBREAKING
TRAGEDY TO ANOTHER OTHER THAN
MAYBE TO CONSIDER ITS PLACE IN
HISTORY.
IT'S HARD TO CONCEIVE SOMETHING
WORSE THAN THIS SCENE YOU'LL
REMEMBER FROM APRIL OF 2007.
A STUDENT KILLED 32 FELLOW
STUDENTS AND FACULTY AT VIRGINIA
TECH IN BLACKSBURG, VIRGINIA.
IT'S THE WORST SINGLE ACT OF GUN
VIOLENCE IN AMERICAN HISTORY.
THE ONLY SCHOOL SHOOTING THAT
INVOLVED MORE FATALITIES THAN
WHAT HAPPENED IN CONNECTICUT AND
SO FAR FOR SO MANY OF US, TODAY
WAS ALSO A REMINDER OF THIS DAY
ON APRIL 20, 1999.
THAT IS WHEN THE NOW INFAMOUS
NAMES, DILL LEANCALLY BOLD --
DYLAN KLEBOLD AND ERIC HARRIS.
THAT AT COLUMBINE HIGH SCHOOL.
WE RECALL CHARLES WHITMAN, THE
ENGINEERING STUDENT AND FORGER
MARINE WHO KILLED 13 PEOPLE AND
AN UNBORN CHILD AND WOUNDED 32
OTHERS IN A SHOOTING RAMPAGE
FROM THE TOWER OF THE UNIVERSITY
OF TEXAS.
THAT WAS ON AUGUST 1, 1966.
HIS MURDEROUS RAMPAGE CAUGHT ON
TV CAMERA.
>> Gregg: NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
IS A TIGHT-KNIT COMMUNITY AND
HOW SOME OF THOSE WHO CALL THE
TOWN HOME ARE SPEAKING OUT ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED AND WHAT IT WILL
TAKE TO GET THROUGH THIS.
>> YESTERDAY HE SAID MY SCHOOL
IS DEAD.
THE KIDS ARE STILL -- HE SAID
NO, MOM.
THE SCHOOL IS DEAD.
MRS. HOCHSPRUNG ISN'T GOING TO
BE THERE AND WE'LL ALL KNOW WHEN
WE GO TO SCHOOL.
SO IF MY SCHOOL FOR ME IS DEAD.
I THINK IN HIS WAY, IT'S NEVER
GOING TO BE THE SAME.
>> WE ARE ALL A QUIET LITTLE
TOWN THAT NOTHING EVER HAPPENS.
NOW SUDDENLY WE'RE IN THE RECORD
BOOKS, NOT BECAUSE SOMEONE WON
THE LOTTERY LAST WEEK, BUT FOR
SOMETHING ELSE.
>> WE KNOW SO MANY PEOPLE.
I CAN'T GO TO THE GROCERY STORE
WITHOUT MEETING PEOPLE THAT
MIGHT KNOW AND I JUST CAN'T
IMAGINE WHAT'S GOING ON IN THE
STORES NOW WHEN PEOPLE MEET EACH
OTHER.
WE'RE GOING TO BE TALK BEING
THIS FOR YEARS.
THE PAIN WILL LAST FOR YEARS.
>> WE'RE GOING TO COME BACK.
IT WILL ALWAYS BE IN OUR MINDS,
JUST AS 9-11 IS ALWAYS ON OUR
MINDS.
I HAVEN'T FELT THIS WAY SINCE
9-11.
BUT THE TOWN IS RESILIENT.
WE'RE GOING TO COME BACK AND
WHAT CAN I TELL YOU?
>> Gregg: THE NATION JOINING
NEWTOWN RESIDENTS IN THEIR GRIEF
TODAY AS WELL.
>> Heather: OUT OF THIS TRAGEDY
WE ARE HEARING HEROIC STORIES OF
THE SANDY HOOK SCHOOL STAFF,
SACRIFICING THEMSELVES TO SAVE
THE LIVES OF THE STUDENTS.
AND THAT INCLUDES PRINCIPAL DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG, TOWN OFFICIALS SAY
THAT SHE DID NOT HESI HESITATE ,
RUNNING INTO THE HALLWAY,
STRAIGHT FORT GUNMAN AND LUNGING
AT HIM.
HE REPORTEDLY THEN SHOT AND
KILLED HER.
OTHER TEACHERS PROTECTING THEIR
STUDENTS BY LOBBING THEIR
CLASSROOM DOORS, HIDING CHILDREN
TO KEEP THEM SAFE AND ONE
TEACHER REPORTEDLY READING
STORIES TO THE KIDS TO TRY TO
KEEP THEM CALM WHILE ANOTHER
27-YEAR-OLD VICTORIA SOTO, YOUNG
FIRST GRADE TEACHER, HID HER
STUDENTS IN A CLOSET BEFORE THE
GUNMAN KILLED HER.
SANDY HOOK'S LIBRARY CLERK
DESCRIBED WHAT SHE DID ONCE SHE
REALIZED HER KIDS WERE IN
DANGER.
>> WE KNEW, I TOLD THEM WHEN WE
STARTED ON THE INTERCOM IN THE
OFFICE WENT OFF, AND THEN WE
HEARD SCUFFLING NOISES AND STUFF
AND I THOUGHT SOMEBODY HAD HIT
THE BUTTON BY MISTAKE AND THEY
WERE IN THE OFFICE.
SOY CALLED DOWN THERE AND ONE OF
THE SECRETARIES ANSWERED THE
PHONE AND SAID THERE IS A
SHOOTING.
AND THEN YOU BECOME AWARE.
WE STARTED HEARING THE GUN
SHOTS.
SO I YELLED LOCKDOWN TO THE
GROUP IN OUR ROOM AND I RAN
ACROSS THE HALL AND TOLD THE
CLASSROOM ACROSS IT WAS A
LOCKDOWN.
THE ONE ACROSS THE HALL FROM ME.
I THINK SOME OF THE KIDS WERE
SCARED, BUT THEY'RE SCARED EVEN
WHEN IT'S A DRILL.
IT'S A SCARY THING.
EVEN WHEN WE HAVE OUR FIRE ALARM
DRILLS.
WHEN IT GOES OFF, YOUR
ADRENALINE STARTS GOING.
IT'S SCARY FOR LITTLE KIDS.
I DON'T THINK UNTIL WE OPEN THE
DOOR AND THERE WAS 15 STATE COPS
WITH THESE GIGANTIC GUNS AND
FEDERAL AGENTS ESCORTING THE
KIDS OUT DID THEY REALLY --
>> WHAT WAS GOING THROUGH YOUR
MIND IN THE CLOSET?
WHAT THE CHILDREN WERE SAYING?
>> IF YOU HAVE AN IDEA OF HOW
LONG DID IT TAKE?
>> WE DIDN'T KNOW -- WE WOULDN'T
LET THEM IN AT FIRST.
SO THEY WERE POUNDING ON THE
DOOR SAYING THEY WERE POLICE AND
THEY HAD SOMEONE CALL US AND
THEY ALSO PUT A BADGE UNDER THE
DOOR AND THAT'S WHEN WE MOVED
THE FIRE CABINETS AND STARTED
LETTING THE KIDS OUT TO THEM.
>> Heather: HO HONOR THEIR
BRAVERY, HUG A TEACHER SIGNS ARE
HANGING THROUGHOUT THE TOWN.
>> Gregg: THE SCHOOL TRAGEDY
DRAWING EMOTIONAL REACTION ALL
OVER THE COUNTRY.
PARENTS CAN SYMPATHIZE WITH
THOSE WHEN LOST THEIR CHILDREN
IN NEWTOWN, BUT AS WE ALL TRY TO
MAKE SENSE OF THIS TRAGEDY, HOW
DO WE EXPLAIN IT TO OUR OWN
KIDS?
DOMINIC WITH ATTEND OF THE
STORY.
>> IT'S AN EXTREMELY HARD THING
TO DO.
YOU GOT TO REMEMBER THE KIDS
ACROSS THE NATION WERE EXPOSED
TO THESE EVENTS IN REAL TIME
THROUGH FACEBOOK.
PSYCHOLOGISTS ARE SAYING PARENTS
REALLY DON'T WANT TO LET THEIR
KIDS GET CARRIED AWAY NOW BY
TWEETS AND UPDATES AND ADVISING
PARENTS TO CALMLY EXPLAIN THE
ACTUAL FACTS AND START
DISCUSSING THE CHILD'S FEELINGS
AND THEIR FEARS AS WELL.
THESE ARE SOME OF THE TYPICAL
QUESTIONS YOU SHOULD ASK.
>> WHAT DID YOU THINK?
WERE YOU EVER AFRAID THAT THAT
COULD HAPPEN AT YOUR SCHOOL?
WELL, WHAT IF IT HAPPENED AT
YOUR SCHOOL?
LET ME TELL YOU WHAT WOULD
HAPPEN, THE TEACHERS WOULD STEP
IN.
THE POLICE WOULD BE THERE.
MOMMY AND DADDY WOULD RUSH TO
THE SCHOOL OR WHATEVER AND SO
DON'T BE AFRAID TO LET YOUR KID
EXPRESS AND PUT WORDS TO AND
TALK ABOUT WHAT'S ALREADY INSIDE
OF THEM.
>> DESPITE WHAT KIDS ARE READING
ON-LINE OR HEARING IN THE SCHOOL
YARD, PSYCHOLOGISTS SAY IT'S
STILL VERY IMPORTANT FOR YOU TO
CONSIDER THE AGE AND HOW MUCH
APPROPRIATE DETAIL YOU GIVE
THEM.
ONE CHILD EXPERT SAYING THE
YOUNGER THEY ARE, THE MORE
DIFFICULT THAT IS FOR A PARENT
TO DO.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> SOMEONE OF A YOUNG SCHOOL
AGE, THEY MIGHT NOT APPRECIATE
THE PERMANENCY OF DEATH.
IS JOHNNY GOING TO BE AT THE
NEXT SOCCER MATCH, OR WHEN WILL
I GET TO SEE HIM?
SO SOMETIMES THERE MIGHT BE
REPEATED QUESTIONS.
THEY MIGHT HAVE TO TALK ABOUT IT
FOR A PERIOD OF TIME.
LET IT GO.
COME BACK AGAIN.
>> GREGG, ALSO HARD TO DEAL WITH
IS THE FACT THAT THE VERY YOUNG
KIDS, THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
THEY ENCOUNTER THEIR OWN SENSE
OF MORTALITY.
YOU MAY NEED TO EXPLAIN TO THEM
THAT THE REPLAY OF EVENTS
THEY'RE SAYING ON TV ISN'T A
PERPETUAL CONVENIENT WHERE
THEY'RE IN AN ENVIRONMENT OF
CONTINUOUS DEATH.
IT MAY BE WHY IT'S GOOD TO TURN
THE TV OFF OR IT COULD TRIGGER
PTSD.
OR IT'S IMPORTANT SAY THE
PSYCHOLOGISTS THAT PARENTS
INSURE THAT KIDS DON'T DEVELOP A
FEAR OF GOING TO SCHOOL.
PSYCHOLOGISTS SAYING THEY NEED
TO MAKE SURE THAT KIDS ARE IN
CLASS ON MONDAY AND ENCOURAGE
THEM THAT IT IS OKAY, THAT IT'S
SAFE TO GO BACK TO SCHOOL,
GREGG.
>> Gregg: DOMINIC IN LOS
ANGELES.
THANK YOU.
>> Heather: SADLY, THE MASSACRE
IN CONNECTICUT IS NOT THE FIRST
MASS SCHOOL SHOOTING.
HOW IT COMPARES TO OTHER
TRAGEDIES IN THE LESSONS THAT WE
MAY BE ABLE TO LEARN AS THE
NATION GRIEVES.
CLEANS
EVERYTHING ABOUT
THE ORAL-B POWER BRUSH
IS SIMPLY REVOLUTIONARY.
OUR UNIQUE BRUSH HEAD CLEANS
IN THREE DIRECTIONS
WITH UP TO 50% MORE
BRUSH MOVEMENTS
THAN LEADING
SONIC TECHNOLOGY.
ORAL-B POWER BRUSHES.
GO TO ORALB.COM
FOR THE LATEST OFFERS.
ERIK HARRIS
>> Gregg: THE SHOOTING IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT IS JUST THE
LATEST TRAGEDY OF ITS KIND:  WE
HAVE SEEN, UNFORTUNATELY,
SIMILAR INCIDENTS INVOLVING
ARMED, HEAVILY ARMED GUNMEN LIKE
SUSPECTED SHOOTER ADAM LANZA.
SOME WEARING MILITARY GARB.
SOME PLANNING, KILLING A LARGE
NUMBER OF PEOPLE.
IN 2007 -- EXCUSE ME, 2011,
JARED LOUGHNER TARGETED CONGRESS
ON YOUR CORNER EVENT IN TUCSON,
ARIZONA.
HE SHOT AND KILLED SIX PEOPLE
AND WOUNDED 12 OTHERS, INCLUDING
GABBY GIFFORDS.
LAST JULY, POLICE SAY JAMES
HOLMES WORE A BULLET PROOF VEST
AND OTHER TACTICAL GEAR WHEN HE
OPENED FIRE INSIDE AN AURA MOVIE
THEATER.
12 PEOPLE DIED IN THAT, DOZENS
MORE WERE INJURED.
AND IT WAS APRIL OF 1999 WHEN
TWO YOUNG MEN SHOT AND KILLED 13
PEOPLE INSIDE COLUMBINE HIGH
SCHOOL IN COLORADO.
DR. MICHAEL BAD SUN A FORENSIC
PATHOLOGIST WHO JOINS US.
DO YOU SEE A PATTERN HERE?
>> I THINK THE PATTERN IS YOUNG
MEN, EARLY 20S, NOT WOMEN --
THIS IS LARGELY SOMETHING THAT
YOUNG MEN DO AND THEY OFTEN HAVE
SIGNIFICANT MENTAL ILLNESS THAT
HAS BEEN UNDIAGNOSED AND
UNTREATED.
SOMETIMES BECAUSE THEY'RE
FUNCTIONING ALL RIGHT AND THEY
WEAR SOMETIMES GOTH CLOTHING.
BUT THE PROBLEM IS THIS IS
UNUSUAL AND EVEN WITH THE
MULTIPLE NUMBERS THAT YOU GAVE,
31 OR 41 INCIDENTS, DOES USUALLY
INVOLVE ONE OR TWO PEOPLE.
NOT A MASS MURDER AS HERE WITH
MORE THAN FIVE MURDERS.
>> Gregg: TO THAT END, WILL IT
BE IMPORTANT, THE AUTOPSY OF THE
SHOOTER?
>> YEAH.
THE AUTOPSY IS GOING TO BE VERY
IMPORTANT TO DETERMINE.
FIRST THEY'LL DO A VERY DETAILED
EXAMINATION OF THE BRAIN,
MICROSCOPIC AND ALL THAT.
BUT THEY'LL ALSO GET TOXICOLOGY
TO SEE IF THE INDIVIDUALS HAVE
BEEN ON ANY KIND OF DRUGS.
DRUGS THAT WERE GIVEN BY MENTAL
HEALTH WORKERS BECAUSE SOME --
THERE HAS BEEN CONCERN THAT SOME
OF THE DRUGS GIVEN TO DEPRESSED
PEOPLE CAN MAKE SOME PEOPLE
VIOLENT AND THIS HAPPENED WITH
THE COLUMBINE PEOPLE.
I THINK HARRIS WAS ON ONE SUCH
DRUG.
WHETHER THAT'S A COINCIDENCE OR
NOT, WE DON'T KNOW YET.
BUT THE PHARMACEUTICAL DRUGS
ALSO HAVE TO BE LOOKED AT TO
MAKE SURE THEY DON'T INCREASE
AGGRESSION IN SOME PEOPLE.
>> Gregg: NOW, IT WAS REPORTED
THAT THE BROTHER OF THE SHOOTER
SAID HE SUFFERED FROM A
PARTICULAR KIND OF AUTISM AND A
LOT OF PEOPLE ARE UNDERSTANDABLY
OUTRAGED AT ANY CONNECTION,
THEREFORE.
>> YEAH.
I THINK IN GENERAL, THERE ARE SO
MANY PEOPLE WITH AUTISM AND
ESPECIALLY AS BURGERS WHO ARE
FULLY FUNCTIONING.
LOT OF DOCTORS WITH ASBURGER,
THEY ARE VERY BRIGHT AND
WHATEVER OTHER EMPATHY ISSUES
THERE ARE IS BEING LOOKED INTO.
BUT I THINK THAT -- FROM WHAT
I'VE SEEN, ABSOLUTELY NO
INDICATION THAT PEOPLE WITH
AUTISM OR ASBERGERS HAVE A HIGH
INCIDENT OF KILLING PEOPLE, EVEN
ONE PERSON THAN THE GENERAL
PUBLIC.
>> Gregg: IN TRYING TO DETERMINE
A MOTIVE HERE, THERE IS A WIDE
VARIETY OF IT, I SUPPOSE,  WHICH
CAN BE EXACERBATED BY ANY MENTAL
ILLNESS UNDIAGNOSED.
IT COULD BE A TWISTED EGO
GRATIFICATION THAT'S DERIVED
FROM THE ABILITY TO CONTROL AND
TERRIFY MASS AMOUNTS OF PEOPLE.
>> YEAH.
AND THEN TO SEE YOUR NAME IN THE
NEWSPAPERS OR TO LEAVE A LEGACY
IN THE NEWSPAPERS THAT YOU KNOW
THAT PEOPLE WILL PAY ATTENTION
TO.
THIS IS THE WHOLE PROBLEM THAT
YOU GUYS AND ME GUYS, TOO, ARE
WE CONCERNED ABOUT COPY CATS?
YES.
WHEN THEY SEE ALL THE ATTENTION
THAT'S PAID TO SOMEBODY WHO HAS
NEVER HAD ATTENTION PAID TO THEM
AT ALL, CAN THIS TRIGGER OFF
SOME PEOPLE WHO ARE ON THE VERY
FRINGES OF SOCIETY?
THIS IS SOMETHING THAT CAN'T BE
CONTROLLED.
THIS KIND OF EPISODE IS SO RARE
AND SO UNUSUAL, THAT'S WHY WE'RE
TALKING ABOUT IT, THAT ONE HAS
TO BE CAREFUL ON WHAT TO DO --
WE DON'T WANT AN ARMED STATE.
IF WE HAVE OUR CHILDREN GROW UP
IN SITUATIONS WHERE THERE IS
ALWAYS A POLICE OFFICER AROUND
PROTECTING THEM, THAT ALSO HAS
ITS POTENTIAL HARMFUL EFFECTS.
>> Gregg: CRIMINOLOGIST WITH THE
MINNESOTA DEPARTMENT OF
CORRECTIONS HAS WRITTEN A
HISTORY OF MASS MURDERERS IN
AMERICA AND HE SAID WHILE MASS
SHOOTINGS ROSE BETWEEN THE 1960S
AND 1990S, THEY ACTUALLY DROPPED
IN THE 2000S.
32 IN THE 1980S.
42 IN 1990S.
26 IN THE DECADE SINCE.
>> ONE OF THE THINGS WE HAVE TO
BE CAREFUL OF, AS FAR AS DEATHS
GO, 'CAUSE THESE ARE DEATHS,
PEOPLE, BECAUSE OF BETTER
MEDICAL CARE, THE SAME INJURIES
THAT WOULD KILL PEOPLE IN THE
'60S AND THE '70S DON'T KILL
PEOPLE ANYMORE.
YOU GET SOMEBODY TO A HOSPITAL
QUICKLY ENOUGH AND PEOPLE WHO
WOULD HAVE DIED FROM HEAD
INJURIES OR BULLET WOUNDS IN THE
'60S AND '70S ARE CONVERTD INTO
ASSAULTS.
THAT WOULDN'T HAVE BEEN ANY
DIFFERENCE --
>> Gregg: ALTHOUGH THIS
CRIMINOLOGIST STUDY FOCUSES ON
THE INCIDENTS, NOT THE NUMBER OF
VICTIMS.
SO ONE WONDERS WHETHER -- WHEN
IT HAPPENS, IT SEEMS LIKE IT'S
HAPPENING SO OFTEN AND YET IN
THE LARGER PICTURE, PERHAPS NOT.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
BUT HOWEVER, FOCUSING ON
KINDERGARTEN, I DID A SEARCH OF
KINDERGARTEN AND FIRST GRADE
MASS MURDERS AND THE ONLY ONE
THAT I COULD FIND WAS BIGGER
THAN THIS WAS A MURDER IN
KINDERGARTEN IN THE 1920S IN
BATH, MICHIGAN, WHERE A
TREASURER OF THE SCHOOL BOARD
TOOK A BOMB AND BLEW UP THE
WHOLE SCHOOL.
>> Gregg: RIGHT.
>> THAT'S THE ONLY ONE WHICH
CHILDREN WERE POINTED AT AND
WERE KILLED IN THIS CRUEL WAY.
MOST OF THESE OTHER MURDERS ARE
OLDER PEOPLE.
NOT THAT -- IT'S ITS OWN
PROBLEM, LIKE COLLEGE STUDENTS
IN PARTICULAR, BUT TO TAKE OUT
YOUR VENGEANCE ON SIX-YEAR-OLDS.
>> Gregg: INNOCENT SIX AND
SEVEN-YEAR-OLDS.
>> I THINK THE KEY TO THAT MAY
BE IN THE RELATIONSHIP HE HAD
WITH HIS MOTHER.
>> Gregg: ALL RIGHT.
WE MAY FIND MORE, DOCTOR, THANK
YOU SO MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Gregg: HEATHER?
>> Heather: OKAY.
RYE NOW WE HAVE SOME BREAK NEWS
ON THIS.
A ROBBIE PARKER APPARENTLY, THE
FATHER OF ONE OF THE VICTIMS IN
THE SHOOTING SPEAKING OUT.
LET'S LISTEN IN.
>> THAT I'VE BEEN SEEING IS I
HAVE TWO REALLY GOOD FRIENDS AT
HOME WHO HAVE SET UP A FACEBOOK
PAGE TO HELP RAISE MONEY.
I HAVE SEEN THE NUMBER OF PEOPLE
WHO HAVE COMMENTED AND EXPRESSED
CONDOLENCES.
>> CAN YOU DESCRIBE WHAT YOUR
DAUGHTER LOOKED LIKE FOR US?
DO YOU HAVE A PHOTOGRAPH?
>> THERE IS LOTS OF PICTURES ON
EMILYPARKER FUND PAGE ON
FACEBOOK.
SHE WAS BEAUTIFUL.
SHE WAS BLOND, ALWAYS SMILING.
(INAUDIBLE).
>> HERE AT THE CHURCH LAST NIGHT
THERE WAS A SPECIAL MEETING AND
I WAS GIVEN AN OPPORTUNITY TO
SPEAK ABOUT THAT AS WELL.
IN THAT, I JUST MENTIONED THAT
THE PERSON THAT CHOSE TO ACT IN
THIS WAY WAS ACTING AS A GOD
GIVEN RIGHTS -- OF HIS OWN FREE
AGENCY.
THAT FREE AGENCY IS GIVEN TO ALL
OF US, TO ACT AND CHOOSE TO DO
WHATEVER WE WANT.
AND GOD CAN'T TAKE THAT AWAY
FROM US.
AND I KNOW THAT THAT'S SOMETHING
THAT HE WAS GIVEN AND THAT'S
WHAT HE CHOSE TO DO WITH IT.
I KNOW THAT GOD CAN'T TAKE THAT
AWAY.
I'M NOT MAD BECAUSE I HAVE MY
AGENCY TO MAKE SURE THAT I USE
IT TO DO WHAT I CAN TO DO
WHATEVER I CAN TO ONE, MAKE SURE
THAT MY FAMILY AND MY WIFE AND
MY DAUGHTERS ARE TAKEN CARE OF
AND THAT IF THERE IS ANYTHING I
COULD DO TO HELP ANYBODY AT ANY
TIME ANYWHERE, I WOULD BE
WILLING TO DO THAT.
>> Heather: YOU'VE BEEN WATCHING
A LIVE NEWS CONFERENCE WITH
ROBBIE PARKER, THE FATHER OF ONE
OF THE VICTIMS IN THIS DEADLY
SHOOTING.
HIS DAUGHTER, EMILY, SHE
APPARENTLY WAS JUST SIX YEARS
OLD.
HER BIRTHDAY MAY OF 2006.
YOU HEARD HIM TALKING A LITTLE
BIT ABOUT WHAT FATHER JONATHAN
MORRIS TALKED ABOUT EARLIER, HE
SAYING HE BELIEVES THE SHOOTER
IN THIS INCIDENTIS
GOD-GIVEN FREE WILL FOR EVIL IN
THIS INCIDENT AND HE LOST HIS
DAUGHTER, EMILY, AS A RESULT.
>>> AMERICANS ACROSS THE COUNTRY
HAVING A HARD TIME GRASPING THE
ENORMITY OF THE TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT.
SADLY, THIS IS NOT THE FIRST
MASS SHOOTING OF ITS KIND.
WE WILL TAKE A CLOSER LOOK AT
WHAT WE CAN LEARN, IF ANYTHING,
FROM PREVIOUS TRAGEDYIES
♪
OWE
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
morning because my back
hurt so bad.
The Sleep Number bed
conforms to you.
I wake up in the morning
with no back pain.
I can adjust it if I need
to...if my back's a little
more sore.
And by the time I get up
in the morning, I feel great!
If you have back pain,
toss and turn at night or
wake up tired with no
energy, the Sleep Number
bed could be your
solution.
The Sleep Number bed's
secret is it's air
chambers which provide
ideal support and put you
in control of the
firmness.
And the bed is perfect for
couples because each side
adjusts independently to
their unique Sleep Number.
Here's what clinical
research has found: ® 93%
of participants
experienced back-pain relief.
® 90% reported reduced
aches and pains.
® 87% fell asleep faster
and enjoyed more deep sleep.
For study summaries, call
this number now.
We'll include a Free DVD
and brochure about the
Sleep Number bed including
prices, and models plus a
FREE $50 savings Card.
And how about this?
Steel springs can cause
uncomfortable pressure points.
But the Sleep Number bed
contours to your body.
Imagine how good you'll
feel when your muscles
relax and you fall into a
deep sleep!
I'm not just a back surgeon, I'm
also a back patient.
I sleep on the Sleep
Number bed myself and I
highly recommend it to all
of my patients.
Need another reason to
call?
The Sleep Number bed costs
about the same as an
innerspring but lasts
twice as long.
So if you want to sleep
better or find relief for
your bad back, call now.
Call the number on your
screen for your free
information kit with DVD,
brochure and price list.
Call right now and you'll
also receive a $50 savings
card just for inquiring
about the Sleep Number bed.
Ask about our Risk-Free
30-night in-home trial.
Call now for your FREE
information kit and a FREE
$50 savings card.
Call now!
>> Gregg: HERE IS WHAT WE KNOW
ABOUT THE SHOOTING TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT.
THE DEATH TOLL IS 28.
26 PEOPLE WERE KILLED AT THE
SCHOOL ITSELF.
20 OF THEM ARE CHILDREN.
POLICE SAY THE SHOOTER IS ADAM
LANZA AND HE KILLED HIMSELF.
ALL AROUND THIS TINY CLOSE-NIGHT
COMMUNITY, THE TOWN OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, MOURNERS FROM ALL
OVER SETTING UP MAKESHIFT
MEMORIALS.
MIKE TOBIN JOINS US LIVE FROM
NEWTOWN'S TOWN CENTER.
MIKE?
>> GREGG, IF YOU LOOK BEHIND ME,
YOU MAY NOTICE A FEW THINGS, A
FLAG POLE IN THE CENTER OF TOWN.
THE FLAG IS AT HALF-STAFF.
SOMETHING IS MISSING.
CHRISTMAS DECORATIONS.
THE PEOPLE HERE BEGAN TO FEEL
GUILTY ABOUT CELEBRATING, SO A
LOT OF PEOPLE ELECTED TO TAKE
THEIR CHRISTMAS DECORATIONS
DOWN.
A SMALL TOWN LIKE THIS, EVERYONE
KNOWS SOMEONE TOUCHED BY THIS
TRAGEDY.
SO THEY'RE COMING TOGETHER, A
LOT OF TIMES THEY'RE COMING
TOGETHER AT THE LOCAL CHURCH
WHERE SOME OF THE MAKESHIFT
MEMORIALS ARE BUILDING UP.
THEY'RE GRIEVING TOGETHER,
TRYING TO MAKE SENSE OF WHAT YOU
CAN'T MAKE ANY SENSE OF AND
STILL AT THE SAME TIME, HELPING
EACH OTHER GET THROUGH.
>> OUR NEIGHBOR DOWN THE STREET
LOST A LITTLE BOY, SIX-YEAR-OLD.
A GOOD FRIEND OF MINE FOUND OUT
THAT HIS SON LOST TWO KIDS ON
HIS BASEBALL TEAM.
SIX YEARS OLD.
I DON'T GET IT.
>> MY BEST ANSWER IS STICK
TOGETHER AND SUPPORT EACH OTHER,
THAT'S WHY WE'RE HERE.
SUPPORT EACH OTHER.
DID I KNOW ANYBODY?
DOESN'T REALLY MATTER.
THEY'RE KIDS.
>> THEY'RE GETTING HELP FROM
PEOPLE OUTSIDE OF THIS
COMMUNITY.
GRIEF COUNSELORS HAVE COME IN
FROM ALL NEIGHBORING STATES AND
SET UP IN NEIGHBORING SCHOOLS.
ONE COUNSELING FOR ADULTS AND
ANOTHER FOR CHILDREN.
A LITTLE EXTRA EFFORT IN MAKING
SURE THE KIDS CAN BE AS
COMFORTABLE AS POSSIBLE AS THEY
TRY TO EXPLAIN WHAT THEY ARE
GOING THROUGH.
THEY HAVE A LOT OF TOYS.
THEY HAVE THERAPY DOGS AND
INCIDENTALLY, THOSE TOYS, STUFF
ANIMALS, THINGS TO MAKE THEM
COMFORTABLE, HAVE BEEN DONATED
BY PEOPLE ALL AROUND THE NATION.
>> Gregg: EVERYBODY'S HEARTS GO
OUT TO THE FOLKS IN NEWTOWN.
MIKE TOBIN LIVE AT THE SOON.
THANKS.
>> Heather: THE NATION COMING
TOGETHER TO SUPPORT THE VICTIMS
OF SANDY HOOK IN THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING THERE.
A STREAM OF MOURNERS ARRIVING AT
THE SCHOOL, LEAVING FLOWERS IN
MEMORY OF THE VICTIMS.
THERE ARE TRIBUTES GOING ON ALL
ACROSS THE COUNTRY THIS EVENING.
THOUSANDS OF MILES AWAY, PEOPLE
IN TEMPE, ARIZONA, FEELING THE
PAIN OF THIS TRAGEDY.
THEY OFFERED THEIR CON DELLENCES
AT A CLINIC.
THEY'RE HELPING FOCUS ON THE
GOOD IN SUCH A DARK TIME.
>> WE'RE HERE TO SHOW THAT THERE
IS STILL LOVE, THERE IS STILL
KINDNESS SMEAR WE'RE HERE TO
SHOW OUR SUPPORT.
>> AS A PARENT, YOU SEND YOUR
KIDS OFF TO SCHOOL AND YOU GIVE
THEM KISS AND YOU DON'T THINK
THAT THEY MAY NEVER COME BACK.
>> I HOPE AND PRAY FOR THOSE
FAMILIES, FOR THAT TOWN, THAT
CITY, THAT STATE, THAT THEY CAN
SOMEHOW GET THROUGH.
>> THERE IS NOTHING THAT MAKES
IT BETTER.
THERE IS NOTHING THAT MAKES IT
BETTER.
BUT JUST KNOW THAT THE PARENTS,
THAT WE'RE THINKING ABOUT THEM.
>> Heather: WITH SO MANY PEOPLE
STILL COMING TO GRIPS WITH THE
ENORMITY OF THIS SHOOTING, WHAT
HAVE WE LEARNED, IF ANYTHING F
PREVIOUS TRAGEDY AS SOON AS JOHN
IS A POLICE PSYCHOLOGIST,
ASSISTED WITH THE SHOOTINGS AT
COLUMBINE.
VIRGINIA TECH, AND AURORA,
COLORADO.
FIRST OF ALL, THANK YOU FOR
JOINING US TODAY.
A DAY THAT IS REALLY HARD TO
GRASP FOR SO MANY PEOPLE ACROSS
THIS COUNTRY.
BUT ON APRIL 20, 1999, YOU WERE
ON THE SCENE AT COLUMBINE.
WHAT, IF ANYTHING, CAN WE LEARN
FROM THAT TRAGEDY AND APPLY IT
TO THE ONE THAT'S HAPPENED
YESTERDAY?
>> I THINK WHAT WE CAN LEARN IS
WHAT THESE TYPE OF EVENTS DO IS
THEY SHATTER THE ASSUMPTIONS WE
HAVE ABOUT THE WORLD.
LIKE SOMEBODY WAS SAYING
EARLIER, YOU HAVE AN ASSUMPTION
THAT YOUR CHILDREN ARE GOING TO
COME BACK ALIVE.
THEY'RE NOT GOING TO BE
MASSACRED.
SO WHEN THESE EVENTS HAPPEN,
THEY SHATTER THOSE ASSUMPTIONS.
I THINK WHAT WE LEARN IS HOW DO
WE REBUILD THAT IN A TIMELY
MANNER SO FOLKS CAN CARRY ON.
>> Heather: WHAT TIME FRAME ARE
WE LOOKING AT?
FROM YOUR EXPERIENCES IN THE
PAST WITH COLUMBINE, VIRGINIA
TECH, MOST RECENTLY THE SHOOTING
THAT HAPPENED IN AURORA,
COLORADO WHAT, TIME FRAME ARE WE
LOOKING AT IN TERMS OF LETTING
PEOPLE REBUILD?
>> I DON'T THINK YOU CAN ADD A
TIME FRAME.
13 YEARS AFTER COLUMBINE, AND
FOLKS STILL STRUGGLING.
THE KIDS GO OFF TO COLLEGE AND
THEY THINK THEY'VE HANDLED IT,
THEN SOMEBODY SAYS, YOU'RE FROM
COLUMBINE, AND THEY ASK
QUESTIONS AND IT BRINGS IT UP.
WHAT HAPPENS WITH EACH OF THESE
TRAGEDIES, LIKE THE SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT BRINGS UP THE
FEELINGS FOR FOLKS, THOSE OF
INVOLVED IN THE AURORA AND
COLUMBINE AND BRINGS IT UP AND
YOU HAVE TO PROCESS IT AGAIN.
>> Heather: YOU CALLED THIS
EVENT TOO MUCH, TOO UGLY.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN BY THAT?
>> WHEN WE'RE DEALING WITH
TRAGEDY, THE BIGGEST THING THAT
HAPPENS IS TOO MUCH, TOO UGLY IS
WHAT'S HAPPENING.
THERE IS SO MUCH BAD STUFF, SO
MUCH LOSS, SO MUCH GRIEF, THE
HEART AND THE BRAIN HAS A HARD
TIME PROCESSING IT.
FOR LIKE THE RESPONDERS HERE WHO
HAVE BEEN THROUGH COLUMBINE AND
BEEN THROUGH AURORA, IT'S WHAT
WE CALL TOO MUCH, TOO UGLY, TOO
SIMILAR.
THAT'S WHERE THEY'RE SAYING,
HERE WE GO AGAIN.
FOR THE FOLKS IN CONNECTICUT,
THE LAW ENFORCEMENT, THE
RESPONDERS AND FAMILIES THAT
THEY'VE NEVER GONE THROUGH THIS,
WHAT WE CALL TOO MUCH, TOO UGLY,
TOO DIFFERENT.
IT'S LIKE WE'VE NEVER EXPECTED
ANYTHING LIKE THIS TO HAPPEN IN
OUR COMMUNITY.
>> Heather: WHAT DO YOU SAY TO
POLICE OFFICERS -- AS A POLICE
PSYCHOLOGIST, WHAT DO YOU SAY TO
THOSE FIRST RESPONDERS PRIOR TO
SOMETHING LIKE THIS HAPPENING TO
POSSIBLY PREPARE THEM FOR WHAT
THEY MAY SEE AND INCIDENTS THAT
INVOLVE SPECIFICALLY YOUNG
CHILDREN?
>> YOU KNOW, YOU REALLY CAN'T
PREPARE 'CAUSE WHEN YOU TALK
ABOUT SOMETHING AHEAD OF TIME,
IT'S WITH YOUR BRAIN.
THEN WHEN YOU GO IN THERE, IT'S
WITH YOUR PSYCHE AND YOUR HEART.
SO PRETTY MUCH WHAT WE TRY ASK
TELL THEM IS WHATEVER YOU SEE IS
GOING TO BE REGISTERING INSIDE
AND THOSE ARE THE IMAGES THAT
ARE GOING TO -- WHEN YOU COME
OUT OF THAT BUILDING, THOSE ARE
THE THINGS THAT YOU'RE GOING TO
SEE BEFORE YOU GO TO BED AND
KIND OF PREPARE THEM, WHAT TO
EXPECT SO WHEN THIEF THESE
REACTIONS, WHAT WE CALL
INTRUSIONS, THEY DON'T START
THINKING THIS IS ABNORMAL.
IT'S NORMAL, BUT IT'S
UNCOMFORTABLE.
>> Heather: AND THE IMAGES,
SPEAKING OF IMAGES THAT YOU'VE
SEEN OR WILL SEE, WE ALL KNOW
THE NEXT IMAGES TO COME WILL BE
THOSE 20 SMALL COFFINS OF THESE
20 YOUNG CHILDREN AGES SIX TO
TEN WHO WERE GOSSAMERSLESSLY
KILLED IN THIS INCIDENT.
HOW DO YOU PREPARE US FOR THAT?
>> AGAIN, SAME TYPE OF THING.
KIND OF KNOWING WHAT YOU'RE
GOING TO SEE AND KNOWING THAT IF
YOU HAVE CHILDREN, YOU'RE GOING
TO KIND OF PERSONALIZE IT AND
KIND OF LOOKING AT HOW TO MAKE
SENSE OUT OF IT.
THE DIFFICULTY IS WITH THE
SENSELESS KILLING, YOU CAN'T
MAKE SENSE.
YOU CAN ASK WHY QUESTIONS ALL
DAY LONG, BUT YOU'RE NEVER GOING
TO GET AN ANSWER THAT WILL PUT
IT IN PERSPECTIVE FOR YOU.
>> Heather: ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR TRYING TO
BRING SOME PERSPECTIVE FOR US
TODAY ON THIS DIFFICULT DAY FOR
SO MANY.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Gregg: RIGHT NOW WE ARE
GETTING PICTURES OF TWO OF THE
ADULT VICTIMS OF THE SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
MARY SHERLOCK WITH HER HUSBAND,
MARK.
SHE WAS THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST
WHO WORKED AT THE SCHOOL FOR 18
YEARS.
MARY WAS 56 YEARS OLD.
LAUREN RUSSO.
SHE HAD JUST ACCOMPLISHED HER
DREAM OF BECOMING A FULL TIME
TEACHER AFTER YEARS OF WORKING
AS A SUBSTITUTE TEACHER.
SHE LOVED DANCE, SHE LOVED THE
THEATER.
LAUREN WAS ONLY 30 YEARS OLD.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
SOMETHING MADE YOUR JAW DROP?
CAMPBELL'S HAS 24 NEW SOUPS
THAT WILL MAKE IT DROP OVER,
AND OVER AGAIN.
♪
FROM JAMMIN' JERK CHICKEN,
TO CREAMY GOUDA BISQUE.
SEE WHAT'S NEW FROM CAMPBELL'S.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THEY ARE A GLOWING EXAMPLE
OF WHAT IT MEANS TO BE
THE BEST.
AND AT THIS SPECIAL TIME
OF YEAR,
THEY SHINE EVEN BRIGHTER.
COME TO THE WINTER EVENT
AND GET THE MERCEDES-BENZ
YOU'VE ALWAYS WISHED FOR,
NOW FOR AN EXCEPTIONAL PRICE.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
GLK350 FOR $399 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'VE REACHED THE AGE
WHERE YOU DON'T BACK DOWN
FROM A CHALLENGE.
THIS IS THE AGE OF KNOWING
HOW TO MAKE THINGS HAPPEN.
SOWHY LET
ERECTILE DYSFUNCTION
GET IN YOUR WAY?
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT VIAGRA.
20 MILLION MEN ALREADY HAVE.
ASK YOUR DOCTOR IF YOUR HEART
IS HEALTHY ENOUGH FOR SEX.
DO NOT TAKE VIAGRA IF YOU TAKE
NITRATES FOR CHEST PAIN;
IT MAY CAUSE AN UNSAFE DROP
IN BLOOD PRESSURE.
SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE
HEADACHE, FLUSHING,
UPSET STOMACH,
AND ABNORMAL VISION.
TO AVOID LONG-TERM INJURY,
SEEK IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
FOR AN ERECTION
LASTING MORE THAN FOUR HOURS.
STOP TAKING VIAGRA
AND CALL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU EXPERIENCE
A SUDDEN DECREASE OR LOSS
IN VISION OR HEARING.
THIS IS THE AGE
OF TAKING ACTION.
VIAGRA.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR.
>> Gregg: POLICE SAY THEY HAVE
FOUND QUOTE, VERY GOOD EVIDENCE
THAT WILL ALLOW THEM TO PIECE
TOGETHER A COMPLETE PICTURE OF
WHAT HAPPENED IN NEWTOWN AND
WHY.
BUT IN A CRIME WITH SO MANY
YOUNG VICTIMS, WHAT ARE
INVESTIGATORS LOOKING FOR RIGHT
NOW?
JUDGE JEANINE PIRRO, HOST OF
"JUSTICE" WITH JUDGE JEANINE
JOINS US LIVE FROM NEWTOWN.
WHAT WOULD YOU BE LOOKING FOR,
FORMER D.A. AND JUDGE, WHAT
WOULD YOU BE FOCUSING ON?
>> YOU KNOW, GREGG, AS SOMEONE
WHO HAS RESPONDED TO THESE CRIME
SCENES OF CHILD VICTIMS, I CAN
TELL YOU FIRSTHAND THAT THIS
TAKES AN ENORMOUS TOLL ON ALL OF
LAW ENFORCEMENT.
I DON'T CARE HOW SEASONED THE
DETECTIVE IS OR THE CRIME SCENE
TECHNICIAN.
THIS STUFF IS EVERYONE'SOR.
WHAT THEY'RE LOOKING FOR AND
WHAT THEY HAVE BEEN LOOK FOR IS
THE NUMBER OF SHOTS TO EACH OF
THE CHILD VICTIMS.
THEY'RE COLLECTING SHELL
CASINGS.
THEY'RE TRYING TO MAKE SURE THAT
THEY HAVE THE FORENSICS, ANY
FINGERPRINTS, WAS THERE A SECOND
GUN?
WAS THERE UNEXPENDED SHELLS OR
SHELL CASINGS, AND THEY
TRYING AT THIS POINT TO
ESSENTIALLY DO A MAP OF HOW THIS
HAPPENED, HOW THE SHOTS WERE
FIRED, FROM WHERE, WHERE WERE
THE CHILDREN, AND OF THE
MULTIPLE GUNSHOT WOUNDS THAT WE
KNOW HAPPENED TO THESE CHILDREN,
OR AT LEAST FROM THE GLOCK AND
THE SIG SAUER, WHICH CHILD
SUFFERED THE FIRST SHOT AND
SECOND.
WAS IT A SPRAY OF BULLETS?
WHAT WAS THE TYPE AND THE WAY
THAT THIS EXECUTION OF THESE
CHILDREN WENT DOWN?
THIS IS A HORRIFIC CRIME SCENE.
>> Gregg: THE OTHER CRIME SCENE
IS THE SHOOTER'S HOME.
I MEAN, THAT MAY, IN FACT, IN
MANY WAYS IN SEARCH FOR THE
ANSWER OF WHY, THAT MAY PROVE
MORE PROFITABLE FOR LAW
ENFORCEMENT?
>> YEAH.
WELL, I THINK GIVE US MORE
INSIGHT INTO WHAT WAS DONE AND
WHAT THE SCENARIO OF HOW IT WAS
DONE.
THERE ARE SOME REPORTS THAT THE
MOTHER IS SLEEPING.
WE DON'T KNOW IF THAT WAS
CONFIRMED.
WAS THERE A STRUGGLE?
WERE THERE ISSUES THAT ANYTHING
CAN GIVE US INFORMATION IN LAW
ENFORCEMENT.
IT COULD BE SOMETHING LIKE A
CIGARETTE BUTT OR AN OVERTURNED
LAMP.
IT CAN BE A LETTER.
IT CAN BE SOME KIND OF A
MESSAGE.
AND MAKE NO MISTAKE, THIS KID'S
HARD DRIVE, EVERYTHING FROM HIS
COMPUTER IS BEING ANALYZED,
LOOKED AT, CELL PHONES,
FACEBOOK.
THEY WILL ESSENTIALLY, GREGG, DO
NOT JUST AUTOPSIES ON THESE
LITTLE ANGELS THAT WERE
UNMERCIFULLY KILLED HERE, BUT ON
A PSYCHOLOGICAL AUTOPSY OF THE
SHOOTER.
WHAT DID HE DO?
WHY DID HE DO IT?
WHAT DOES THE TOXICOLOGY TELL
US?
WAS HE ON DRUGS OR MEDS?
THERE IS A GREAT DEAL OF WORK
THAT HAS YET TO BE DONE, EVEN
THOUGH THE SHOOTER IS DEAD.
>> Gregg: HIS MEDICAL RECORDS,
SCHOOL RECORDS WILL ALSO LIKELY
PROVE VALUABLE AS WELL.
JUDGE JEANINE, THANKS VERY MUCH.
YOU CAN CATCH "JUSTICE" WITH
JUDGE JEANINE LIVE FROM NEWTOWN
RIGHT HERE ON THE FOX NEWS
CHANNEL.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK
[ Male Announcer ]
RED LOBSTER'S CRABFEST
ENDS SOON.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OURENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
Is bigger than we think ...
Sometimelike the flu.fer from
With aches, fever and chills-
the flu's a really big deal.
So why treat it like
it's a little cold?
There's something
that works differently
than over-the-counter
remedies.
Prescription TAMIFLU attacks
the flu virus at its source.
So don't wait. Call your
doctor right away.
TAMIFLU is prescription
medicine for treating the flu
in adults and children
one year and older
whose flu symptoms started
within the last two days.
Before taking TAMIFLU tell your
doctor if you're pregnant,
nursing. have serious
health conditions,
or take other medicines.
If you develop an allergic
reaction, a severe rash,
or signs of unusual behavior,
stop taking TAMIFLU and call
your doctor immediately.
Children and adolescents in
particular may be at an
increased risk
of seizures, confusion
or abnormal behavior.
The most common
side effects are
mild to moderate nausea
and vomiting.
The flu comes on fast,
so ask your
doctor about TAMIFLU.
Prescription for flu.
>> Heather: THE AMERICAN FLAG
FLYING AT HALF-STAFF AT THE
WHITE HOUSE AS THE NATION MOURNS
THOSE KILLED IN THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
PRESIDENT OBAMA DEDICATING HIS
WEEKLY ADDRESS TO THE TRAGEDY.
MOLLY HENNEBERG IS LIVE WITH THE
VERY LATEST, THE REACTION COMING
IN FROM WASHINGTON.
MOLLY?
>> HEATHER, OUR HEARTS ARE
BROKEN TODAY.
THAT'S WHAT PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID
IN HIS WEEKLY RADIO AND INTERNET
ADDRESS.
AS YOU SAID, HE ADOPTED THE
ENTIRE ADDRESS TO THE SHOOTING
IN CONNECTICUT AND SAID THE
NATION GRIEVES FOR THE FAMILIES
WHO LOST LOVED ONES.
>> THIS WEEKEND MICHELLE AND I
ARE DOING WHAT I KNOW EVERY
PARENT IS DOING, HOLDING OUR
CHILDREN AS CLOSE AS WE CAN AND
REMINDING THEM HOW MUCH WE LOVE
THEM.
THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CAN'T DO THAT
TODAY AND THEY NEED ALL OF US
RIGHT NOW BECAUSE WHILE NOTHING
CAN TAKE THE PLACE OF A LOST
CHILD OR LOVED ONE, ALL OF US
CAN EXTEND A HAND TO THOSE IN
NEED, TO REMIND THEM THAT WE'RE
THERE FOR THEM.
>> THE FLAGS ARE LOWERED TO
HALF-STAFF AT BOTH THE WHITE
HOUSE AND THE CAPITOL IN HONOR
OF THOSE WHO WERE KILLED.
REPUBLICANS IN CONGRESS USUALLY
DO A WEEKLY ADDRESS OF THEIR OWN
ON SATURDAY.
BUT NOT TODAY.
GOP HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER
SAID THERE WOULD BE NO
REPUBLICAN ADDRESS SO THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA COULD SPEAK FOR
THE ENTIRE NATION, QUOTE, AT
THIS TIME OF MOURNING.
SPEAKER BOEHNER DID SAY IN A
PAPER STATEMENT, QUOTE, THE
HORROR OF THIS DAY SEEMS SO
UNBEARABLE, BUT WE WILL LOCK
ARMS AND UNITE AS SIDSS, FOR
THOSE HOW AMERICANS RISE ABOVE
UNSPEAKABLE EVIL.
LET US ALL COME TOGETHER IN
GOD'S GRACE TO PRAY FOR THE
FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS THAT
THEY MAY FIND SOME COMFORT AND
PEACE AMID SUCH SUFFERING.
THERE ARE SOME IN CONGRESS
CALLING FOR TIGHTER GUN CONTROL
LAWS IN THE WAKE OF THE
SHOOTING.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID IN THAT
ADDRESS TODAY THAT THE COUNTRY
NEEDS TO, QUOTE, TAKE MEANINGFUL
ACTION TO PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS.
HEATHER.
>> Heather: MOLLY HENNEBERG LIVE
FOR US FROM WASHINGTON.
THANK YOU.
>> Gregg: SO AS WE APPROACH THE
EVENING HOUR, WE'RE ENDING
PRETTY MUCH WHERE WE BEGAN, NO
REAL GOOD ANSWERS AS GOVERNOR
DAN MALLOY EXPRESSED IN HIS
STATEMENT TO THE CITIZENS OF
CONNECTICUT.
THE DAYS AHEAD MAY CHANGE ALL OF
THAT.
>> Heather: WILL BE VERY TOUGH,
ESPECIALLY AS MORE INFORMATION
COMES OUT ABOUT THESE TINY
YOUNG, INNOCENT VICTIMS.
GOVERNOR MALLOY ALSO SAYING WE
MOVE FORWARD FROM HERE WITH
LOVE, COMPASSION AND COURAGE.
>> Gregg: A LOT OF PRAYERS ALONG
THE WAY AS WELL.
WE THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US
ON THIS DIFFICULT DAY, BUT OUR
COVERAGE DOES CONTINUE WITH
SPECIAL TWO-HOUR FOX REPORT WITH
BILL HEMMER WHO IS LIVE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
HE'S COMING UP NEXT.
AS THE GOVERNOR SAID, HUG
SOMEONE A LITTLE BIT TIGHTER
TODAY.
BYE-BYE
initiated.
Neural speeds
increasing to 4G LTE.
Brain upgrading to a quad-core
processor.
Predictive intelligence
with Google Now complete.
Introducing DROID DNA by HTC.
It's not an upgrade
to your phone.
It's an upgrade to yourself.
TILL YOU FINISH YOUR VEGETABLES.
[ clock ticking ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THERE'S A BETTER WAY...
V8 V-FUSION.
VEGETABLE NUTRITION THEY NEED,
FRUIT TASTE THEY LOVE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
OR...TRY KIDS BOXES!
AND YOU LEARNED SOMETHING
ALONG THE WAY.
THIS IS THE AGE OF KNOWING
WHAT YOU'RE MADE OF.
SO, WHY LET
ERECTILE DYSFUNCTION
GET IN YOUR WAY?
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT VIAGRA.
20 MILLION MEN ALREADY HAVE.
ASK IF YOUR HEART
IS HEALTHY ENOUGH FOR SEX.
DO NOT TAKE VIAGRA IF YOU TAKE
NITRATES FOR CHEST PAIN;
IT MAY CAUSE AN UNSAFE DROP
IN BLOOD PRESSURE.
SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE
HEADACHE, FLUSHING,
UPSET STOMACH,
AND ABNORMAL VISION.
TO AVOID LONG-TERM INJURY,
SEEK IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
FOR AN ERECTION
LASTING MORE THAN FOUR HOURS.
STOP TAKING VIAGRA
AND CALL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU EXPERIENCE
A SUDDEN DECREASE OR LOSS
IN VISION OR HEARING.
THIS IS THE AGE
OF TAKING ACTION.
VIAGRA.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR.
SEE IF AMERICA'S
MOST PRESCRIBED ED TREATMENT
IS RIGHT FOR YOU.