THEY BOTH IN CONTACT WITH
POLICE.
THEY ARE IMPORTANT IN THIS
INVESTIGATION.
POLICE OFFERED MORE CLARITY
ABOUT THE WEAPONS USED IN THIS
HORRIFIC ASSAULT.
A BUSHMASTER AR 15 ASSAULT RIFLE
COUPLED WITH HIGH CAPACITY
MAGAZINES WAS THE PRIMARY WEAPON
USED IN THE ATTACK.
THE GUNMAN CARRIED WITH HIM TWO
SIDE ARMS A 6 MILLIMETER AND 10
MILLIMETER.
ONE OF THE GUNS WERE USED BY THE
GUNMAN TO KILL HIMSELF WHEN
FIRST ARRIVED ON THE SCENE.
A SHOT GUN ACCORDING TO POLICE
THAT WAS LEFT OUT IN THEIR CAR
DURING THIS ATTACK.
POLICE ALSO INDICATED THAT THEY
ARE GATHERING EVIDENCE AND
INFORMATION ABOUT A MOTIVE BUT
AT THIS STAGE OF THE
INVESTIGATION THEY ARE NOT
PREPARE TO DO OFFER UP ANY
PARTIAL INFORMATION.
>> YOU SIMPLY CAN'T PIECEMEAL
IT.
WE DON'T HAVE A SPECIFIC REASON
WE CAN STAND HERE AND SAY THIS
OCCURRED.
WE WILL AND WE ARE SEARCHING
DILIGENTLY AND NONSTOP TO ANSWER
THAT QUESTION.
>> ALSO TODAY TROOPERS SAID
AUTOPSIES ARE COMPLETED ON THE
FINAL TWO BODIES MOVED ON THE
CRIME SCENE.
THOSE WERE THE BODIES OF THE
GUNMAN AND HIS MOTHER NANCY
LANZA.
SHE HAD GUN SHOT WOUNDS TO THE
HEAD.
THEY ARE GIVING MORE DETAILS SHE
WAS KILLED BY FOUR GUN SHOT
WOUNDS IN THE HEAD.
SHE WAS FOUND IN HER BED STILL
WEARING NIGHT CLOTHES.
THE GUNMAN WAS KILLED BY A
SINGLE GUN SHOT WOUND TO THE
HEAD.
GOVERNOR?
>> THANK YOU FOR THAT REPORT.
>> THE CONNECTICUT SHOOTER'S
BROTHER TOLD POLICE HIS BROTHER
HAD AUTISM OR ASPERGER'S
SYNDROME AS WELL AS A
PERSONALITY SYNDROME.
CAROLYN SPECIALIZES IN MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES.
IN YOUR EXPERIENCE WHEN A PERSON
HAS CERTAIN BEHAVIORS LIKE WE
HAVE SEEN IN THE SHOOTER.
ARE ANY OF THESE DISORDERS THE
TYPE THAT WOULD EXHIBIT
THEMSELVES IN THIS MANNER?
>> NOT IN A MANNER TO WHICH WE
HAVE SEEN IN THE LAST SEVERAL
DAYS BUT THERE ARE SIGNS AND
SYMPTOMS THAT LEAD UP TO CERTAIN
BEHAVIORS.
SO IF YOU KNOW WHAT TO LOOK FOR
THE RED FLAGS AS I CALL THEM YOU
KNOW HOW TO IDENTIFY THEM YOU
CAN ACTUALLY GO BACK AND SEE
WHAT COULD BE PROBLEMATIC.
>> BUT TO PUT PARENTS AT EASE
WHO MAY HAVE A CHILD WHO HAS
EITHER AUTISM OR ASPERGER'S A
PRESENCE OF SOME FORM OF AWE
SICHL OR ASPERGER'S SUBJECT MAKE
THEM SAY MY CHILD IS A MASS
MURDERER JUST BECAUSE OF THE
DISORDER.
>> IT IS REALLY THE BEHAVIORS
YOU WANT TO LOOK AT.
IT'S THE CHANGE IN BEHAVIORS HAD
A ARE REALLY OF CONCERN.
YOU HAVE A CHILD WHO IS DOING
WELL IN SCHOOL, SOCIALLY ACTIVE,
IS BEHAVING APPROPRIATELY AND
SUDDENLY THERE'S A CHANGE THEY
BECOME MORE ISOLATE TIVE THEY
BECOME MORE SOCIALLY
UNENGAGEABLE.
THEY DON'T WANT TO TO GO TO
SCHOOL THEIR GRADES GO DOUVENL
THOSE SHOULD BE SIGNS TO PARENTS
TO TAKE A LOOK AT AND PUT INTO
CONTEXT THE BEHAVIOR AND ANY
SYMPTOMS OR ANY DIAGNOSES THAT
MAY BE AT PLAY.
>> THE REASON I WANT TO DELVE
INTO THIS A LITTLE BIT.
I THINK SOME PARENTS SAY I DON'T
HAVE TO WORRY ABOUT MY CHILD
BECAUSE HE DOESN'T HAVE
ASPERGER'S OR ANY FORM OF
AUTISM.
THAT'S NOT NECESSARILY A VALID
CONCLUSION EITHER IS IT?
>> NO, IT'S NOT.
THERE ARE FIRST OF ALL AUTISM IS
A SPECTRUM DISORDER.
SO THERE ARE MANY DIFFERENT
BEHAVIORS AND SYMPTOMS ALONG THE
WAY.
IN ADDITION THERE ARE OTHER
DISORDERS THAT ARE AT PLAY.
THERE ARE SERIOUS MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES AND MAL LODY DISORDERS,
CHARACTER LOGICAL DISORDERS.
YOU NEED TO FOCUS IN ON WHAT IT
IS YOU ARE TALKING ABOUT.
WE TRY VERY HARD TO ASCERTAIN A
DIAGNOSIS OR A WORKING DIAGNOSIS
AND THEN GO FROM THERE AND SORT
OUT WHAT ARE OUR EXPECTATIONS
WHAT CAN WE EXPECT TO BE FIRST
WHAT CAN WE EXPECT TO BE TREATED
WHAT INTERVENTIONS CAN WE BRING
TO BEAR?
WE WORK AS A TEAM APPROACH SO
THAT WE CAN BRING IN MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS, CASE
MANAGERS FOR EXAMPLE,
PSYCHOLOGISTS DIE KIE TERRORISTS
WHO ADDRESS EACH INDIVIDUAL
SYMPTOM BASED ON WHAT IS GOING
ON PSYCHOLOGICALLY AND I
PSYCHIATRICALLY.
>> OUR AUDIENCE HEARD A LOT OF
WORDS THROWN AT THEM OVER THE
WEEKEND.
WORDS THAT YOU USE EVERY DAY IN
THE COURSE OF YOUR PRACTICE OF
LAW AND PSYCHOLOGY BUT MOST
PEOPLE DON'T USE THESE WORDS
MAYBE THEY ARE NOT FAMILIAR TO
THEM.
WHEN WE SAY THAT A PERSON IS A
PSYCHOTIC, HAS PSYCHOTIC
BEHAVIORAL TENDENCIES WHAT DOES
THAT MEAN?
>> THAT USUALLY MEANS A BREAK
WITH REALITY.
YOU ARE NOT ABLE TO SEE THINGS
REALISTICALLY YOU ARE NOT
PROCESS THINGS COMING IN IN A
REALISTIC WAY.
>> AND A SOCIOPATH WHAT DOES IT
MEAN IF A PERSON IS DESCRIBED AS
SOCIOPATHIC?
>> SOCIOPATHS IS A CHARACTER
LOGICAL DISORDER.
IT IS MANIFEST BY USUALLY PEOPLE
WHO CAN'T FEEL, THEY DON'T HAVE
EMPATHY.
THEY DON'T CONNECT TO THE USUAL
DAY-TO-DAY FEELINGS THAT MOST OF
US CAN CONNECT TO.
>> SO SOME PEOPLE COULD BE SOME
WHAT PSYCHOTIC AND SOCIOPATHIC,
IS IT POSSIBLE TO BE A PERSON
WITH BOTH CHARACTER RYES
RISTICKS?
>> FROM THE MENTAL HEALTH
EXPERTS I WORK WITH EVERY DAY I
BELIEVE THE ANSWER TO THAT WOULD
BE YES.
>> SO THAT'S WHAT I WANT TO MAKE
SURE PEOPLE UNDERSTAND.
THIS IS VERY COMPLEX.
IT'S NOT LIKE YOU CAN TAKE A
CHILD AND SAY HE HAS ASPERGER'S
THEREFORE HE IS MORE LIKELY TO
DO A MASS MURDER AND BY THE WAY
THAT MEANS HE IS PSYCHOTIC.
IT INVOLVES A COMPLEX KIND OF
DIAGNOSIS.
>> A COMPLEX DIAGNOSIS AS WELL
AS PUTTING IT INTO CONTEXT AND
REALLY LOOKING AT HOW TO ACCESS
IN THE REAL WORLD.
THE TREATMENTS MIGHT BE
INTERVENTION GETTING HELP IT'S
THE BIGGEST WE FACE.
HAVING MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES THIS
THEY CAN GET PAST THAT HURDLE
THEY ARE MORE OPEN TO ALLOWING
EXPERTS IN THE FIELD TO
INTERVENE AND TRY AND HEAD OFF
ANY PROBLEMS DOWN THE ROAD.
>> YOU CARRY THE STIGMA.
IT IS VERY DIFFICULT.
I FEEL FOR FOR PARENTS WHO ARE
AFRAID TO SAY MY CHILD MAY HAVE
A MENTAL ILLNESS.
YOU HAVE THE CHILD SAYING
THERE'S SOMETHING WRONG WITH ME
THAT'S DIFFERENT.
YOU NEED TO HELP PEOPLE
UNDERSTAND THAT A MENTAL ILLNESS
IS NO DIFFERENT THAN A PHYSICAL
INFIRMITY.
WE DON'T SAY A PERSON HAS A
BROKEN LEG THAT WOULD BE
EMBARRASSING SOMEBODY MIGHT
THINK MY CHILD HAS A BROKEN LEG
OR A PEND SITET-- APPEND SITETI.
HOW CAN WE GET PEOPLE WHERE AS
IT WERE COMPARABLE TO ANY
PHYSICAL ILLNESS WE MAY HAVE.
>> I SAY IN MY PRACTICE TO MY
CLIENTS EVERY DAY.
THAT GOES BACK TO THE
CONVERSATION THEY NEED TO HAVE
WITH ONE ANOTHER.
WITH THEIR PHYSICIANS WITH OTHER
MENTAL HEALTH PROFESSIONALS WITH
WHOM THEY WORK WITH THE MENTAL
HEALTH ATTORNEYS.
THEY NEED TO HAVE THAT
CONVERSATION AND SAY EXACTLY
THAT IT'S A BRAIN CHEMISTRY
ISSUE IT'S ILLNESS.
IF YOU HAVE A HEART PROBLEM YOU
GO TO THE CARDIOLOGIST.
IF YOU BREAK YOUR LEG YOU PUT A
CAST ON IT.
IT HAS BEEN SO MANY DECADES OF
PEOPLE HAVING THAT STIGMA AND
THINKING IT'S BAD.
ALSO THE PUBLICITY THAT GOES
WITH IT.
EVERY TIME THERE IS A TRAGEDY
SUCH AS THE ONE WE HAVE SEEN
THIS WEEK THE FIRST QUESTIONS
ASKED ARE IF YOU HAVE A MENTAL
ILLNESS RATHER THAN WHAT WENT ON
WITH THIS INDIVIDUAL OR WHAT
MIGHT READ LED UP TO IT OR WHAT
ISSUES ARE WE FACING.
YOU NEED TO DE STIGMATIZE IT AS
MUCH AS WE CAN.
>> IT IS AN IMPORTANT THING THAT
HAS TO HAPPEN.
HOPEFULLY AT SOME POINT IN OUR
CULTURE THERE HAS BEEN A COMMON
DENOMINATOR SEEMINGLY.
A LOT OF THESE MASS SHOOTINGS
INVOLVING YOUNG PEOPLE OR EVEN
CHILDREN THE COMMON DENOMINATOR
IS THE PROLIFIC MANNER IN WHICH
MANY OF THESE KIDS PLAYED VERY
VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES.
I WANT TO BE CAREFUL NOT TO
IMMEDIATELY DRAW THE LINE FROM
THE VIDEO GAMES TO THE BEHAVIOR
BUT THERE DOES SEEM TO BE SOME
CONNECTION.
DO YOU SEE A CONNECTION?
IF SO HOW DO WE DEAL WITH THIS?
>> AGAIN I THINK YOU HAVE TO PUT
ALL OF THIS INTO CONTEXT.
IF YOU ARE SEEING OTHER
BEHAVIORS AND THEY ARE PLAYING
VIDEO GAMES, THERE IS PROBABLY A
BIGGER ISSUE THAN THE VIDEO
GAMES.
THERE IS A LOT OF TALK A LOT OF
RESEARCH BEING DONE ON WHETHER
VIDEO GAMES ACTUALLY LEAVE THE
VIOLENCE.
I THINK IT IS VERY HARD TO
CONNECT UP THE TWO.
WHEN WE TAKE A HISTORY THERE'S A
LOT MORE GOING ON IN THE COURSE
OF THE DISCUSSION THAN JUST MY
SON OR DAUGHTER SPENDS ALL DAY
PLAYING VIDEO GAMES.
I THINK HE NEEDS TO HAVE A
PREDISPOSITION FOR THE VIDEO
GAMES TO ACTUALLY CAUSE YOU TO
THEN TAKE SOME SORT OF NEGATIVE
ACTION OR BECOME VIOLENT.
>> I WANT TO CONTINUE WITH THAT
THOUGHT WE WILL BE RIGHT BACK
WITH CAROLYN WOLF WHEN WE RETURN
WITH THIS SPECIAL EDITION OF
"HUCKABEE.
[ Male Announcer ]
WE ALL MAKE BAD DECISIONS.
LIKE SAY, GAS STATION SUSHI.
CHEAP IS GOOD.
AND SUSHI, GOOD.
BUT CHEAP SUSHI, NOT SO GOOD.
IT'S LIKE THAT SUPER-LOW RATE
ON NOT ENOUGH CAR INSURANCE.
PRETTY SKETCHY.
♪
AND THEN THERE ARE
THE GOOD DECISIONS.
LIKE ESURANCE.
THEIR COVERAGE COUNSELOR TOOL
HELPS YOU CHOOSE
THE RIGHT COVERAGE FOR YOU
AT A GREAT PRICE.
[ stomach growls ]
WITHOUT FEELING QUEASY.
THAT'S INSURANCE
FOR THE MODERN WORLD.
ESURANCE.
NOW BACKED BY ALLSTATE.
CLICK OR CALL.
>> WE ARE BACK.
WE WERE TALKING EARLIER ABOUT
THE VIDEO GAMES AND THE
INFLUENCE THEY HAVE.
I THINK YOU MADE AN IMPORTANT
POINT.
JUST BECAUSE A KID PLAY AS VIDEO
GAME EVEN A VIOLENT ONE DOESN'T
MEAN HE IS GOING TO TURN INTO A
MASS MURDERER.
IF THERE IS A CHILD WHO HAS
CERTAIN THINGS GOING ON IN HIS
HEAD THE DETACHMENT FROM
REALITY, THE INABILITY.
IT COULD BE A TRIGGER POINT TO
TAKE HIM OFF TO WHERE MOST KIDS
WOULDN'T GO.
>> THAT'S THE CONTEXT YOU HAVE
TO PUT THIS INTO.
PEOPLE, PARENTS, TEACHERS,
FRIENDS, WE HAVE AN ISSUE WITH
FRIENDS NOT WANTING TO RAT THEIR
FRIENDS OUT OR TATTLE ON THEM.
FRIENDS OF MANY OF THESE
INDIVIDUALS COULD ACTUALLY BE
VERY HELPFUL IN AT LEAST
BRINGING TO AN ADULT'S ATTENTION
THAT THERE IS AN ISSUE.
THEY PLAY THEIR VIDEO GAMES WITH
A LOT OF THE TIME.
THEY A
THEIR FRIENDS.
I THINK IT NEEDS TO BE LOOKED AT
IN THE BIGGER PICTURE.
WHAT ELSE IS GOING ON IN THE
BIGGER PICTURE IN ADDITION TO
WATCHING THE VIDEO GAMES.
IT COULD ACT AS A TRIGGER.
>> IT IS EASY TO LOOK BACK AT
CERTAIN TYNE SIGNS PEOPLE ARE
SAYING SHE MUST HAVE SEEN
BEHAVIORAL TENDENCIES WITH HER
SON SHE PULLED HIM OUT OF SCHOOL
AND HOME SCHOOLED.
REPORTS ARE SHE HAD A COLLECTION
OF GUNS TAUGHT HIM HOW TO USE
THEM.
TALK ABOUT RED FLAGS THAT YOU
COULD IDENTIFY IN THIS SITUATION
BASED ON WHAT WE KNOW REALIZING
IT'S AN INCOMPLETE PICTURE AT
THIS POINT.
>> WE FOUND WE CAN TRAIN
PARENTS, SCHOOLS, COLLEGE
PERSONNEL, FACULTY TEACHERS TO
IDENTIFY BEHAVIORS.
THEY 2K5DON'T HAVE TO BE EXPERT.
THEY START TO MOVE AWAY FROM THE
NORMAL BEHAVIOR.
A KID WHO SITS IN THE FRONT OF
THE ROOM SUDDENLY IS SITTING IN
THE BACK AND IS QUIET AND
WRITING STRANGE THINGS AND
PARENTS CAN DO THE SAME THING.
THEY CAN NOTICE THEIR CHILDREN
ARE MOERMALNORMALLY HAPPY AND A
AND SOCIAL AND NOW ARE SUDDENLY
ISOLATING SPENDING MORE TIME IN
THEIR ROOMS HAVING TROUBLES IN
SCHOOL.
IT'S REALLY IMPORTANT TO TAKE
SOME SORT OF ACTION RATHER THAN
PULLING THEM INTO THE ICE LAYING
HOME SCHOOLING THEM FOR EXAMPLE.
I AM NOT SAYING THAT MAY NOT BE
APPROPRIATE IN SOME CASES BUT IT
IS ISOLATING.
PARENTS SHOULD GO TO THE SCHOOL
TALK TO THE GUIDE DANCE
COUNSELORS ASK WHAT'S GOING ON.
I AM SEEING A CHANGE AT HOME.
>> THERE ARE ALSO BEHAVIORS THAT
CAN BE TRIGGERED BY FAMILY
SITUATIONS.
YOU HAVE A MOTHER AND FATHER WHO
DIVORCED A FEW YEARS AGO.
THAT CHANGES THE STRUNG TOUR I
AM NOT SAYING YOU BLAME THE
PARENTS BUT IF THE CHILD IS
MANIFESTING CERTAIN BEHAVIORS
BECAUSE OF A DIVORCE A DEATH IN
THE FAMILY A LOSS OF A PET THERE
COULD BE MANY THINGS HAD A HELP
TRIGGER BEHAVIORS.
>> THAT'S WHY WE WORK CLOSELY
WITH PARENTS TO TALK ABOUT THAT.
WHAT IS GOING ON IN THE HOME
WHAT CHANGE LED TO DIFFERENT
BEHAVIORS IN CHILDREN AND THEN
BRINGING IN A TEAM OF MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS WHO CAN
THEN ADDRESS THE CHANGES.
BECAUSE THEY ARE AGAIN EASY TO
IDENTIFY IN A LOT OF CASES YOU
JUST HAVE TO KNOW WHAT TO LOOK
FOR.
>> I THINK PEOPLE ARE AFRAID
SOMETIMES TO RAISE THE FLAG.
THEY ARE VERY RELUCTANT WITH
SCHOOL COUNSELORS AND OTHERS
BECAUSE THEY ARE AFRAID EITHER
OF LIABILITIES OR THEY WILL BE
SEEN AS STICKING THEIR NOSE IN
SOMEONE ELSE'S BUSINESS.
WHERE IS THAT LINE OF PRO PRITY?
OO I THINK AS WE SEE MORE AND
MORE OF THESE INCIDENTS AND
TRAGEDIES THE DIALOGUE IS JUST
STARTING TO BE MORE TOWARDS WE
NEED TO LOOK AT THIS AND TALK
ABOUT IT AND SET UP SYSTEMS TO
ADDRESS IT.
AFTER THE AURORA SHOOTING WE
HEARD ABOUT THE BEHAVIORAL
INTERVENTION TEAMS ON COLLEGE
CAMPUSES THEY ARE SET UP
SPECIFICALLY TO IDENTIFY KIDS AT
RISK OR KIDS REPORTED TO HAVE AT
RISK BEHAVIOR OR RED FLAG
BEHAVIOR.
THEN NOT JUST TO TARGET THEM SO
TO SPEAK OR SPY ON THEM BUT TO
COME UP WITH AN INTERVENTION AND
A RESPONSE THAT IS
MULTIDISCIPLINARY THAT CAN
ADDRESS THE CONCERNS THAT ARE
BEING BROUGHT TO THE FOREFRONT.
I BELIEVE UNFORTUNATELY NOW
SCHOOLS HAVE TO START TO DO
THAT.
IN THE LOWER SCHOOLS IT IS
UNIMAGINABLE YOU WOULD DO THAT
AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL BUT YOU
NEED TO LOOK AT THAT AND NEED TO
DO THAT.
>> CAROLYN THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
VERY HELPFUL AND PRACTICAL.
NICE TO HAVE YOU HERE.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> I HOPE PEOPLE WILL USE THIS
AS AN OPPORTUNITY TO REALIZE IF
THERE IS EVIDENCE OF MENTAL
ILLNESS IN YOUR CHILD OR
YOURSELF THAT YOU DON'T FEEL
LIKE SOMEHOW IT OUGHT TO BE
EMBARRASSING TO GET HELP.
WE OUGHT TO GET TO A PLACE WHERE
IT IS EMBARRASSING TO NOT GET
THE HELP.
I WILL TALK TO ALLEN DEDER S--
ABOUT WHAT HE WOULD LIKE IF HE
WENT TO TRIAL.
>> ALLEN HAS REPRESENTED SOME OF
AMERICA'S MOST REVILED
DEFENDANTS LIKE CLAUSE VAN BEULE
LOW AND O.J. SIMPSON IN THE CASE
OF THE CONNECTICUT SHOOTING THE
GUNMAN IS DEAD.
THERE WILL BE NO TRIAL.
BUT I ASKED THE PROFESSOR HAD
THE GUNMAN LIVED HOW OLD HE
DEFEND SOMEONE RESPONSIBLE FOR
ONE OF AMERICA'S MOST HEINOUS
CRIMES.
>> IT'S THE CALL EVERY GOOD
LAWYER DREADS GENERALLY HAPPENS
A JUDGE WILL CALL YOU AND SAY
YOU ARE A RESPECTED LAWYER, THE
SYSTEM REQUIRES THIS MAN BE
VIGOROUSLY DEFENDED YOU HAVE THE
JOB OF DEFENDING HIM.
YOU HAVE TO DO YOUR VERY BEST.
MY DAUGHTER-IN-LAW IS AN
EMERGENCY DOCTOR AT COLUMBIA
PRESBYTERIAN HOSPITAL.
THEY WHEEL PEOPLE INTO HER WHO
ARE TERRIBLE, TERRIBLE HUMAN
BEINGS SHE HAS TO MAKE THEM
BETTER THE SYSTEM REQUIRES THAT.
IN THAT CAA CASE LIKE THIS YOU
LOOK INTO HIS MENTAL BACKGROUND
YOU SEE IF THERE'S A PLAUSIBLE
CLAIM OF MENTAL ILLNESS.
YOU KNOW IF HE GOES TO JAIL HE
WILL BE KILLED IN JAIL.
THE WORST TREATMENT ARE GIVEN TO
PEOPLE WHO KILLED YOUNG CHILDREN
UNDERSTANDABLY SO, AND SO IT IS
ALWAYS GOING TO BE A LIFE AND
DEATH MATTER EVEN IF HE IS
FACING LIFE IMPRISONMENT.
>> YOU HAVE PERSONAL FEELINGS
YOU HAVE TO SET ASIDE.
>> IT IS SO HARD.
YOU WANT TO SEE THIS SOB GET THE
LONGEST POSSIBLE SENTENCE.
THE FIRST INCLINATION IS YOU
WANT TO STRANGLE THE MAN WITH
YOUR BARE HANDS.
WE HAVE ALL EXPERIENCED THAT.
YOU HAVE TO DISTANCE YOURSELF BE
PROFESSIONAL ABOUT IT AND YOU
HAVE TO REMEMBER THE SYSTEM IS
ON TRIAL WHEN EVER THE MOST
NOTORIOUS OFFENDERS.
I REMEMBER BEING IN REAL SHORTLY
AFTER THE EICHMANN TRIAL WHEN A
MAN WHO KILLED IS RESPONSIBLE
FOR KILLING 6 MILLION JEWS WENT
ON TRIAL.
HE HAD A VIGOROUS DEFENSE
ATTORNEY WHO DID A GOOD JOB.
COULDN'T SAVE THEM, OBVIOUSLY
BUT THAT'S THE DREADED MOMENT
EVERY LAWYER FACES IS BEING
CALLED ON TO HIS OR HER DUTY IN
A CASE LIKE THIS.
>> IS THERE A TENDENCY TO TRY TO
GET THAT PERSON TO PLEAD GUILTY
TO GET IT OVER WITH AND TAKE A
PLEA DEAL AS OPPOSED TO GOING
THROUGH TRIAL OR PLEAD INNOCENT?
DO YOU ACTUALLY SAY DO YOU WANT
TO PLEAD INNOCENT?
>> YOU GIVE THE PERSON ALL OF
THE OPTIONS.
THEY GENERALLY DON'T WANT TO
PLEAD GUILTY.
THEY ALSO DON'T WANT YOU TO
PLEAD AN INSANITY DEFENSE.
THEY WANT YOU TO GET UP THERE
AND JUSTIFY IT AND EXPLAIN TO
THE WRORLD WORLD WHY HE DID THE
THING.
POLITICAL DEFENSES AREN'T
ALLOWED AND SHOULDN'T BE
ALLOWED.
BUT DEALING WITH THE CLIENT WILL
BE ONE OF THE HARDEST THINGS.
I HAVE HAD CLIENTS THREATEN ME
ONE CLIENT TRY TO STRANGLE ME.
HE HAD BEEN TURNING ON HIS
FRIENDS.
BEING A CRIMINAL DEFENSE LAWYER
IS NOT THE SAFEST OR EASIEST
JOB.
IF YOU WIN, WHICH IN A CASE LIKE
THIS YOU COULDN'T, THEN MILLIONS
OF PEOPLE HATE YOU AND WANT TO
GET YOU I HAD TO HAVE A FEDERAL
AGENT FOLLOW ME AROUND BECAUSE I
WOULDN'T TAKE THE CASE ANY MORE.
THE PERSON I WOULDN'T TAKE THE
CASE FROM PUT A HIT OUT ON ME.
>> WE HAVE TO ASK THE QUESTION,
WHY IS IT IMPORTANT TO DEFEND
SOMEONE IF WE KNOW -- NOT JUST
KNOW HE'S GUILTY BUT KNOW HE IS
GUILTY OF SOMETHING SO
OUTRAGEOUS SO HEINOUS THERE IS
NOT A PERSON IN THIS SOCIETY
THAT DEFENDS THE ACTION OF THE
PERSON WHO DID IT?
>> IT IS A VERY GOOD QUESTION.
ONCE YOU SAY THERE ISN'T ANYBODY
WHO CAN GET A DEFENSE WHICH
PROVIDE ALL DEFENDANTS MUST BE
VIGOROUSLY DEFENDED THEN WE MOVE
THE LINE WHAT IF WE ARE ALMOST
CERTAIN HE DID SOMETHING SO WERE
TERRIBLE EVEN INNOCENCE
SHOULDN'T BE A DEFENSE.
YOU VISSER RATE THE BASIC
FUNDAMENTAL DEFENSES.
OUR JOB IS TO DEFEND THE SOB'S.
COME AFTER THEM FIRST.
THEN THEY APPLY THE LAW TO THE
REST OF US.
EVERY TIME YOU DEFEND A
HORRIBLE, HORRIBLE PERSON YOU
ARE DEFENDING SOMEBODY WHO LOVES
YOU AND YOU LOVE AND YOU MAY BE
IN TROUBLE STATEMENT IN TIME.
SOME SAY A LIBERAL WHO HAS BEEN
MUGGED.
THERE'S TRUTH TO THAT.
A KID HAS BEEN BUSTED ON A
CHARGE AND REALLY NEED YOU TO
COME AND DPEE FEND HIM ON THE
BASIS OF THE 6TH AMENDMENT OR
4TH AMENDMENT.
THE GREATNESS OF AMERICA IS THAT
OUR RIGHTS APPLY TO EVERYBODY.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO AGREE WITH
RIGHTS.
IF I WERE WRITING THE
CONSTITUTION I WOULD NOT PUT A
SECOND AMENDMENT IN THERE.
>> BUT IS IT IS IN THERE AND I E
TO DEFEND THE RIGHT OF PEOPLE
REASONABLY REGULATED TO BE SURE
BUT THE RIGHT OF PEOPLE TO HAVE
ACCESS TO GUNS.
WE MAY NOT LIKE EVERYTHING IN
THE CONSTITUTION BUT IT SERVED
US VERY WELL.
THE LONGEST ENDURING
CONSTITUTION IN HISTORY IT AIN'T
BROKE WE SHOULD NOT BE TAMPERING
WITH IT.
>> I AM SO GLAD YOU SAID THAT.
I THINK SOMETIMES WE FORGET WHAT
AN AMAZING DOCUMENT.
THEY CAME TOGETHER AND
MIRACULOUSLY ENDED UP WITH A
DOCUMENT THAT GOVERNED US AND
GIVEN US A GOVERNMENT THAT IS
THE ENVY OF THE CIVILIZED WORLD.
>> IT IS A MIRACLE.
IT COULDN'T HAPPEN TODAY.
WE COULD NEVER GET AGREEMENT
TODAY ON THE FIRST AMENDMENT
WHAT DOES IT MEAN ABOUT PRAYER
IN THE SCHOOLS.
COULDN'T GET AN AGREEMENT ON THE
5TH AMENDMENT.
WE WERE FORTUNATE TO GET A
COLLECTION OF RIGHTS.
THIRD AMENDMENT YOU CAN'T
QUARTER TROOPS IN YOUR HOME.
BUT THAT DEALS WITH PRIVACY
RIGHTS.
THE HOME IS YOUR CASTLE.
WHEN THE EASTERN EUROPEAN GOT
THEIR UNION WAS DEFEATED THE
FIRST CONSTITUTIONS THEY LOOK TO
WAS THE UNITED STATES
CONSTITUTION.
>> A GREAT REMINDER WE HAVE A
SYSTEM.
WE DON'T JUST LET OURSELVES BE
GOVERNED BY OUR EMOTIONS BUT BY
OUR CONSTITUTION AND LAWS.
>> OUR SYSTEM GOES ON TRIAL
EVERY TIME WE SEE A CAT CAST FEE
LIKE THIS ONE.
>> THANK YOU.
>> THERE ARE MANY QUESTIONS
ASKING ABOUT THE SHOOTING IN NEW
TOWN.
THE MOST ASKED QUESTION IS
PROBABLY WHY.
IS THERE AN ANSWER TO THAT
QUESTION?
I WILL ASK PASTOR JOEL OLSTEEN
AND HIS WIFE VICTORIA NEXT.
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
AAH!
LEARNING HOW TO KICK FLIP
6 STAIRS TAKES DETERMINATION.
SO WILL GETTING INTO COLLEGE.
I'VE GOT WHAT IT TAKES.
SO DO YOU.
>> LIVE FROM AMERICA'S NEWS
HEADQUARTERS I AM MARIANNE
RAFFER
RAFFERTY.
LAW AMERICAS ARE FACING A FULL
WORKLOAD.
THEY ARE VOTING ON AN AID
PACKAGE TORE SUPER STORM SANDY.
THEY REPLENISH THE FEDERAL
PROGRAMS.
GOVERNORS OF NEW YORK, NEW
JERSEY AND CONNECTICUT RO URGING
CONGRESS TO GET IT DONE BEFORE
THEY GO HOME FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
VICE PRESIDENT OF SYRIA SAYING
THE REBELS CAN'T WIN BUT NEITHER
CAN GOVERNMENT FORCES.
AFTER 21 MONTHS OF CIVIL WAR
UNLIKELY EITHER SIDE COULD WIN A
DECISIVE MILITARY VICTORY.
HE DOESN'T BELIEVE THE REBELS
ARE THE SOLUTION TO SYRIAN
PROBLEMS AND THAT IF THEY WON IT
MIGHT BRING CHAOS TO THE
COUNTRY.
HE ALSO SAID HE DOESN'T THINK
THE ASSAD REGIME CAN ACHIEVE
NEEDED CHANGE.
I AM MARIANNE RAFFERTY NOW BACK
TO HUCKABEE.
FOR THE LATEST HEADLINES GO TO
I AM STILL VERY NUMB
AND JUST LIKE ROBERT HAD SAID WE
ARE BLESSED WITH HAVING OUR
DAUGHTER WITH US HERE TODAY.
HOW MANY FAMILIES AND FRIENDS
AND EVERYONE WITHIN THE
COMMUNITY DIDN'T GO HOME WITH
THEIR CHILDREN FRIDAY NIGHT.
IT IS JUST VERY, VERY HEART
WRENCHING AND THERE IS NO WAY TO
MAKE ANY SENSE OF ANYTHING WITH
THIS PERSON HAS DONE.
>> NOW THAT THE VICTIMS OF THE
SHOOTING AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HAVE BEEN
IDENTIFIED THE COMMUNITY IS
FOCUSING ON REMEMBERING AND
HONORING THOSE WHO HAVE BEEN
LOST.
LET'S GO TO FOX'S AN TAW KOOIMAN
IN SAINT ROSE CHURCH IN NEWTOWN.
>> AS THE NATION SEARCH
THEY HAD QUITE A SCARE AS LAW
ENFORCEMENT RUSHED INTO THEIR
BUILDINGS AND OTHER PLACES ON
CAMPUS TODAY.
>> NEW FOUND POLICE AND A SOAKS
PERSON SAY A CALL CAME IN WHERE
A MAN THREATENED TO KILL PEOPLE
IN A CHURCH.
EVERYTHING IS OKAY.
BUT NOT BEFORE AN EVACUATION.
>> THE PAST INTERRUPTED PEOPLE
LEFT VERY CALMLY AND GREAT
DIGNI
DIGNITY.
WE PRAY THERE WILL BE MOW MORE
ON THIS CAMPUS TODAY.
THE FUNERALS WILL BE HELD LATER
IN THE WEEK AND THE PRIESTS ARE
REPAIRING FOR IT AND STILL
WORKING WITH FAMILIES.
WARNING WAS THERE A FELLOW
NEIGHBOR DISHEARTENED.
THIS IS ALREADY THE TOUGH DATE
FOR THE COMMUNITY.
AS THE MEDICAL EXAMINER 12 GIRLS
8 BOYS AN 6 ADULTS OCCURRED.
THEY LOST MANY OF THE PLAYMATES
AND FAVORITE TEACHERS.
THIRD GRADER ALI CARRIES AROUND
A PICTURE OF HER TEACHER
VICTORIA SOTO.
>> MY FAVORITE FIRST GRADE
TEACHER.
>> THEY HAVE NO WAY TO HELP THE
VICTIM'S FAMILIES EXCEPT THEY
ARE SAFE AND PRAYER.
CHURCH OFFICIALS LOCKED UP THE
SANCTUARY SAYING THE PRIESTS
HAVE A LOT TO PREPARE FOR.
8 OF THE 26 VICTIMS ARE FROM
THIS PERISH ALONE, GOVERNOR.
>>> WHEN A TRAGEDY LIKE THIS
HAPPENS.
I AM UNDOUBTEDLY ASKING WHY.
>> I SPOKE WITH JOEL OLSTEEN AND
HIS WIFE.
WHAT DO YOU TELL PEOPLE WHEN
THEY ASK HIM.
WHY DIDN'T THEY STOP SOMETHING
LIKE THIS FROM HAPPENING.
>> I THINK THE BIGGEST THING WE
HAVE TO UNDERSTAND IS GOD SAGAV
US OUR OWN FREE WILL.
HE DIDN'T MAKE US ROBOTS.
UNFORTUNATELY JUST AS YOU CAN
CHOOSE GOOD OR EVIL.
IT'S NOT A PERFECT PLACE.
JESUS CAN'T SAY IN THIS WORYOU
GOING -- YOU PUT YOUR TRUST IN
THE LORD AND HE WILL GIVE YOU
THE STRENGTH TO MAKE IT THROUGH
EVEN THOUGH IT'S DIFFICULT.
>> WHEN PEOPLE LOOK AT THAT
STRENGTH HOW DO THEY FIND IT?
OP WHY YOU WILL PEOPLE WHO BRAY
OUT TO GOD IN PRAYER.
THEY HEAR ABOUT PRAYER, NEVER NE
DON IT.
WHAT DO THEY DO?
>> I THINK IT'S SO IMPORTANT.
TO ME IT'S FINE TO BE.
I THINK YOU ARE HONEST WITH GOD
SCRIPTURE SAYS MY ENCOURAGEMENT
A LOT OF PEOPLE BET BIGGER HE
WOULDN'T HAVE LET THIS HAPPEN.
I GO THE OPPOSITE DIRECTION I
SAY IN THESE TOUGH TIMES I AM
GOING TO TURN TO MY FAITH AND
BELIEF GOD IS FOR ME.
IT'S A SIMPLE ACT OF FAITH.
IT MAY NOT MAKE SENSE TO YOUR
MIND YOU HAVE GOD HAS GOT YOU IN
THE HAND.
>> SO MANY PEOPLE ARE TRYING TO
FIND THE SOLID GROUND OF THEIR
FAITH RIGHT NOW.
THERE'S NO WAY TO MAKE SENSE
WHAT HAPPENED TO THE CHILDREN
WELLS TO THE EACHTEACHERS.
WHAT ADVICE DO YOU GIVE THEM FOR
PEOPLE WHO ARE TRYING TO GET
BACK THEIR FAIRT IN A MOMENT
WHEN DE THIS HAVE ANY HUMAN
UNDERSTANDING AND HUMAN WORDS TO
EXPRESS HOW THEY FEEL.
>> THERE ARE NO HUMAN WORDS TO
EXPLAIN WHAT HAS HAPPENED OR AT
THIS PARTICULAR MOMENT GIVE
COMFORT.
BUT I BELIEVE AS THE COMMUNITY
GATHERS TOGETHER AS THEY SUPPORT
ONE ANOTHER, IF THEY LOVE ONE
ANOTHER.
THERE ARE A LOT OF TIMES WHEN
SOMETHING DEFR STATES TO US.
WE HAVE TO RUN TO GOD TO BELIEVE
HE HAS LOVED US AND HE CARES
ABOUT US AND WE CAN GIVE
THROUGH.
>> VICTORIA YOU ARE A MOM.
I AM SURE THIS WEEKEND HAS
BROUGHT UP TEEP EMOTIONS TO
EVERY MOTHER IN AMERICA.
WHAT DID YOU SAY TO YOUR OWN
CHILDREN THIS WEEKEND ABOUT THIS
HORRIFIC GLAM CRIME.
WHAT HAPPENED AND WHY?
>> THE FIRST THING WE DID IS WE
PRAYED FOR THOSE FAMILIES.
WE BEGAN TO TALK ABOUT HOW THIS
IS DIFFICULT FOR THE FAMILIES.
THERE IS NO EXPLANATION FOR WHAT
HAD HAPPENED.
THERE IS PEOPLE THAT DO THINGS
THAT THEY SHOULDN'T DO AND THERE
IS EVIL IN THE WORLD.
BUT THE WAY I BEGIN TO SAY IS
LET'S PRAY FOR THESE FAMILIES
AND LIFT THEM UP.
THAT'S OUR PART RIGHT NOW.
OF COURSE YOU REALLY CAN'T
EXPLAIN WHY SOMEONE DOES OR
DOESN'T DO WHAT THEY DO.
IT WAS AN EVIL ACT.
I JUST THINK SOMETIMES WE HAVE
TO SAY LET'S PRAY AND JOIN OUR
FAITH TOGETHER WITH THESE
FAMILIES.
WE MAY NOT KNOW THEM BUT WE CAN
PRAY FOR THEM AND PRAYER MAKES A
DIFFERENCE.
>> THE PRESIDENT SHOWED AN
UNUSUAL LEVEL OF EMOTION CHOKING
BACK OBVIOUS TEARS AS HE
RECOGNIZED THESE WERE KIDS VERY
MUCH LIKE HIS OWN AND IT
OCCURRED TO ME THIS IS A MAN WHO
MAY BE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES BUT HE IS A DAD.
I THINK HE SPOKE AND FELT FOR
EVERY FATHER IN HIS COUNTRY WHEN
HE TODAY AT THAT PODIUM TRYING
TO ACKNOWLEDGE WHAT HAPPENED THE
FEELINGS AS A DAD HOW DOWRY
ASSURE YOUR KIDS WE DOO TO BE
AFRAID THE NEXT TIME WE THENT ON
THE SIDEWALKS AND THE STREETS.
>> YOU HAVE TO BELIEVE GOD HAS
YOU IN THE FALL AM OF HIS HANDS
AND NOTHING WITH SNATCH YOU
AWAY.
THE NUMBER OF DAYS GOD WILL
FULFILL.
WE UNDERSTAND IT WHY SOME KIDS
WERE TAKEN OTHERS WERE NOT.
WE TO TRUST GOD IS IN CONTROL.
NOT LIVE YOUR LIVES BITTER.
WE PRAYED AND THEN IT REIGNITED
OUR FAITH LET'S REACH OUT TO
OTHERS.
WE TALKED ABOUT GOVERNOR -- IT
HELPS YOU TO APPRECIATE EACH DAY
AS A GIFT.
THERE'S NO GUARANTEE WE WILL
HAVE TOMORROW WITH EACH OTHER.
I HOPE WE DO.
IT REALLY HELPS TO GET OUR
PRIORITIES RIGHT?
HAVE I TOLD MY FAMILY HOW
MUCH -- MAKE SURE WE TAKE EACH
GIFT.
DEEP EXPRESSIONS OF LOVE AND
APPRECIATION.
WILL HE WESTBOUND LIGHT BACK
SAKE TORYA OLSTEEN WHEN WE
RETURN.
>> BACK WITH JOEL AND VICTORIA
OLSTEEN FROM THEIR CHURCH IN
HOUSTON TEXAS.
DID YOU WATCH YOUR KIDS WATCH
THE COVERAGE ON THE NEWS AND HOW
DID YOU MONITOR TO MAKE SURE IT
WASN'T TOO MUCH OF AN EMOTIONAL
OVER LOAD FOR THEM?
>> OUR CHILDREN ARE 17 AND 14.
THEY ARE A LITTLE OLDER THAN IF
I HAD FIRST, SECOND GRADERS.
IT IS REALLY A HARD THING, WAS
EVERY WHERE YOU LOOK THEY ARE
TALKING ABOUT IT.
I THINK THERE'S GOOD REPORTS OUT
THERE.
THEY ARE TALKING ABOUT THE HEROS
THAT CAME THROUGH EVEN THOUGH
THEY COST HEAR LIFE THE TEACHERS
WHO TOOK THE CHILDREN UNDER HEAR
WINGS AND BEGAN TO PROTECT THEM.
THERE ARE THOSE HEROS.
YOU CAN ALSO FOCUS ON THE FACT
THAT THERE WERE CHILDREN WHO
MADE IT OUT THERE ARE HEROS.
FAMILIES CAN COME TOGETHER THE
COMMUNITY WILL BE STRONGER.
IT IS A SMALL COMMUNITY.
THEY WILL COME TOGETHER AND BE
STRONG AND TALK ABOUT THE
OUTCOME IF THERE IS A GREAT
LOSS.
GOD STILL IS IN CONTROL.
THERE ARE STILL GOOD DAYS AHEAD.
>> OUR SOCIETY HAS BECOME SO
CYNICAL VERY SECULAR.
THEY REJECT THE NOTION THAT
FAITH IS A LITTLE MORE THAN SOME
EMOTIONAL PRACTICE WE GO
THROUGH.
HOW CAN PEOPLE RECOGNIZE THERE
IS SOMETHING MORE SUBSTANTIVE
GOING ON FAITH AND PRAYER IS
REAL?
IT DOES EFFECT THE WAY THAT WE
LIVE AND THINK AND RELATE TO THE
TRAGEDIES OF OUR LIVES.
A LOT OF PEOPLE FEEL IT'S US
MAKING OURSELVES FEEL BETTER BY
SAYING WORDS THAT MIGHT AS WE
WILL BE ABRACADABRA.
>> I DON'T KNOW HOW YOU CAN MAKE
THEM.
ONE WAY YOU LIVE BY XAVRP.
SOMETIMES TRAGEDIES THRIVE THEM
TO KNOW THE LORD.
I AM LIKE YOU ONCE YOU HAVE
TASTED WHAT IT MEANS TO FEEL THE
LORD AND YOU FEEL THE PEACE AND
STRENGTH THAT HE GIVES YOU CAN'T
TAKE THAT AWAY.
THERE WILL ALWAYS BE PEOPLE THAT
DON'T UNDERSTAND IT WE SEE THAT
BACK IN THE BIBLE EVEN SAUL OF
TAR SUS BUT GOD KNEW HOW TO GET
HIS ATTENTION.
I THINK A BIG PART OF OUR
MINISTRY IS SPREADING HOPE
SAYING GOD IS FOR YOU HE'S GOOD
AND IT DOES MAKE A DIFFERENCE TO
SERVE HIM TO HONOR HIM WITH YOUR
LIFE.
IT'S NOT JUST THE GOOD TIMES BUT
THE TOUGH TIMES.
LIKE VICTORIA SAID YOU DON'T RUN
AWAY FROM GOD YOU RUN TO GOD AND
SAY GOD MY HEART IS BREAKING.
HOW COULD THIS HAPPEN.
YOU ARE HONEST WITH GOD THAT'S
WHEN YOU SEE -- YOU WILL FEEL
GOD'S PEACE LIKE YOU HAVE NEVER
FELT BEFORE.
>> I KNOW YOU BOTH SPEAK TO
MILLIONS OF PEOPLE EVERY WEEK
FLEW TELEVISION AND THERE AT
LAKEWOOD.
I APPRECIATE YOUR SHARING AN
ENCOURAGING MESSAGE AND A
MESSAGE OF HOPE TO ALL WHO ARE
WATCHING TONIGHT.
JOEL VICTORIA OSTEEN, GOD BLESS
YOU.
>> GOD BLESS YOU.
APPRECIATE YOU.
>> I WILL BE BACK WITH CLOSING
THOUGHTS.
>> I SAID CONTROVERSIAL THINGS
FROM TIME TO TIME BUT NONE AS
WHEN I STATED THE HORRIFIC
SHOOTING IN SCHOOLTEACHERS
COULDN'T BE BLAMED ON GOD
BECAUSE WE MARGINALIZED GOD
RIGHT OUT OF OUR CULTURE BY
REMOVING HIM FROM ALL ASPECTS OF
THE PUBLIC SQUARE.
THE VICIOUS ATTACKS THAT
RESULTED MOST ALL OF WHICH ARE
BASED ON TOTAL IGNORANCE OF WHAT
I ACTUALLY SAID HAVE VALIDATED
MY POINT.
BUT I AM QUITE CERTAIN THAT WAS
NOT THE INTENT OF THE
PROFESSIONAL AND AMATEUR CRITICS
WHO DEMANDED EVERYTHING FROM MY
BEING BANNED FROM EVER SPEAKING
IN PUBLIC AGAIN OR EVEN WHO WISH
ME A SLOW AND PAINFUL DEATH.
ON THAT ALONE, I WISH TO
ACKNOWLEDGE THAT THE IT HAS
SHOWN IT DEFINES TOLERANCE AND
DIVERSITY AS BEING TOLERANT ONLY
OF THAT WITH WHICH IT AGREES AND
THE VERSE ONLY TO INCLUDE SIDE
SHADES OF THE ORTHODOX
LIBERALISM OF WHICH THEY HEAR.
THEY ABORE CENSORSHIP OF GRAPHIC
VIOLENCE BUT THE FIRST TO DEMAND
A VOICE THAT INVOKES THE NAME OF
GOD OUGHT TO BE SILENCED.
A SPECIFIC ACT OF VIOLENCE IS
RARELY THE RESULT OF A SPECIFIC
SINGLE ACT OF A CULTURE THAT
PROMPTS IT.
I WOULD NEVER SAY SIMPLY TAKING
PRAYER AND BIBLE READING FROM
OUR INSTITUTIONS OR SILENCING
CHRISTMAS CAROLS IS THE DIRECT
CAUSE OF A MASS MURDER.
THAT WOULD BE LUDICROUS AND
SIMPLIST
SIMPLISTIC.
BUT THE CAUSE AND EFFECT WE SEE
AN THE CHANGES OF WHAT OUR
CHILDREN ARE CAPABLE OF IS A
PART OF A CULTURAL SHIFT FROM A
GOD CENTERED CULTURE TO A SELF
CENTERED CULTURE.
GLORIFY UNINHIBITED SIEELF
EXPRESSION AND THEN WE ARE
SHOCKED WE HAVE A GENERATION OF
LOAN ANOTHERS.
WE HAVE INSISTED ON A SOCIETY
WHERE EVERYONE GETS A TROPHY AND
NO ONE LOSES AND THEN ACT
SURPRISED SO MANY KIDS LACK
SELF-ESTEEM AND FEEL LIKE
LOSERS.
WE DISMISS THE NOTION OF NATURAL
LAW AND THE MOTINOTION THAT THE
ARE MORAL ABSOLUTES AND SEEM
AMAZED WHEN SOME KIDS MAKE IT
THEIR OWN MORALITY TO KILL
INNOCENT CHILDREN.
WE DIMINISH EVEN HOLD IN
CONTEMPT THE NATURAL FAMILY OF A
FATHER AND MOTHER CREATING AND
RESPONSIBLY RAISING THE NEXT
GENERATION AND THEN EXPRESS
DISMAY THAT KIDS FEEL NO REAL
CONNECTION TO THEIR FAMILIES OR
EVEN THE CONCEPT OF A FAMILY.
WE SCOFF AT THE NEED FOR MOTHERS
AND FATHERS TO MAKE IT THEIR
PRIORITY TO TRAIN THEIR CHILDREN
TO BE STRONG IN SPIRIT AND SOUL
AND BE RESPONSIBLE FOR RIGHT AND
WRONG AND EXALT INSTEAD THE VIR
S
DUE OF HAVING THINGS PROVIDING
EXPENSIVE GAMES TOYS THAT
SUBSTITUTE FOR PARENTING.
DON'T UNDERSTAND WHY OUR KIDS
WOULD HAVE EAR BUDS DANGLING TO
THE EARS FINGERS ATTACH TO DO A
SMART PHONE AND FACE ATTACHED TO
A COMPUTER SCREEN RATHER THAN
HAVE EXTENDED CONVERSATION WITH
THEIR FAMILY AT DINNER.
WE DON'T TEACH THEM THERE'S A
CREATOR GOD WHO SETS RULES A GOD
WHO IS KNOWABLE AND TO WHOM WE
ARE ULTIMATELY RESPONSIBLE.
WE TEACH THEM GOD WAS NOT
INVOLVED IN OUR ORIGINS.
OUR VERY LOIFS WERE BIOLOGICAL
HAPPEN STANCES THOSE ARE
DISPOSABLE SHOULD THEY BE
INCONVENIENT.
BEHAVIORS ARE NOT SIN BUT
DISORDERS FOR WHICH WE OUGHT TO
BE EX CLUED AT LEAST
ACCOMMODAT
ACCOMMODATED.
I REALIZE IT IS MORE OUTDATED
AND ARCHAIC.
IF IT WAS FROM THE SOCIAL
CONTRACT WE GOT IN TROUBLE FOR
SCHOOL FOR TALKING ACRASS.
PULLING A GIRL'S PIGTAILS OR
SLOUCHING IN HER SCHOOL DESK.
WE TOOK GUNS TO BE SCHOOL TO BE
SURE.
WE USED THEM BEFORE AND AFTER
SCHOOL
SCHOOL.
THEY WERE IN OUR TRUCKS.
IT NEVER OCCURRED TO HER.
I SHOULD STAND THE CONTEMPT AND
CRITICISM.
I WILL GLAD LIE ACCEPT THEIR
TORN WITH A DESTEADY STREAM.
I AM SOME KIND OF AN IDIOT.
IS BUT WHEN WE AS A NATION
FEARED GOD WE DIDN'T FEAR THAT A
20-YEAR-OLD WITH A HIGH POWERED
RIFLE WOULD GUN DOWN OUR
CHILDREN IN THEIR SCHOOL ROOMS.
FROM NEW YORK, THIS IS MIKE
HUCKABEE.
IDEA FIGHNIGH
-- GOOD NIGHT.
GOD BLESS.