EVERY FOD SERVICE EMPLOYEE AND
SECRETARY AND PRINCIPAL AND
TEACHER AND VOLUNTEER HAS TO
BE TRAINED AND IMPOWERED AND
PRABITIS TO MAKE LIFE OR DEATH
DECIGS WITHOUT WAITING FOR
INSTRUCTIONS .
I AM GETTING INDICATIONS THAT
THAT OCCURRED IN THE AT THE
SAME TIMES FROM PUBLIC SAFETY
AND LIEUTENANT VANCE AND SO
FORTH.
THE DRILLS ARE DEFINITELY
EXTREMELY IMPORTANT.
REVERSE THE EVACUATION AND
LOCK DOWN AND THEY ARE LIFE
SAVING PROTOCOL THAT NOT ONLY
TALK TO PEOPLE BUT PROVIDE THE
PRACTICE AND IMPLEMENT THEM
WISTLY.
A A 10 SECOND DELAY INCREASES
THE NUMBER OF PEOPLE KILLED OR
INJURY .
A PORNOGRAPHY OR FIRE OR ANY
SUCH EVEN.
NTHE TRAINING IS MORE THAN THE
ARMORING AND AFFECTS ON THE
SCHOOL.
MUC MOTORCYCLE.
THARCHING YOU.
NTHANK YOU, SIR.
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE, HIGH
AND HIS CREW WERE HERE JUST AN
HOUR GOING GIVING A NEW'S
CONFERENCE.
AND KEEPING AN EYE OUT FOR A
VEHICLE TO COME IN IN ANY
MOMENT FOR THE SUPERINTENDENT.
WE ARE WAITING AN UPDATE OUT
OF NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT WHERE
WE EXPECT TO SEE THE DETAILS
OF WHAT TRANSFIRED AND THE
PROFILE OF THE KILLER AHEAD .
[ Woman ] Ring. Ring.
Progresso.
In what world do potatoes,
bacon and cheese
add up to 100 calories?
Your world.
♪
[ whispers ]
Real bacon...
Creamy cheese...
100 calories...
[ Chef ] Ma'am
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
But when I was in an accident...
100 calories...
[ Chef ] Ma'am
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
So I never missed a beat.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.
AND HIS NEW BOSS TOLD HIM
TWONGS --
COOK WHAT YOU LOVE,
AND SAVE YOUR MONEY.
JOE DOESN'T KNOW IT YET,
BUT HE'LL WK HIS WAY UP
FROM BUSSER TO WAITER TO CHEF
BEFORE OPENING A RESTAURANT
SPECIALIZING IN FISH AND ME
FROM THE GREAT NORTHWEST.
HE'LL START INVESTING EARLY,
HE'LL FIND SOME GOOD PEOPLE
TO HELP GUIDE HIM,
ND HE'LL SET MONEY ASIDE
FROM HIS FIRST DAY OF WORK
TO HIS LAST,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
STATE POLICE IN CONNECTICUT
HAVE UNCOVERED EVIDENCE THAT
WILL POINT TO HOW AND WHY THIS
HORRIFIC SHOOTING TOOK PLACE
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
INE AS WE LEARN NEW DETAILS
ABOUT THE SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA
SEEN HERE IN A 2005 PHOTO,
WILL WE EVER KNOW WHAT
MOTIVATED HIM?
DR. STONE IS A CLIPICAL
PSYCHETRIST.
YOU HAVE LOOKED AT HUNDREDS OF
THEM OVER THE YEARS.
>> COMMONALITY IN MASS MORES
IS THE ELEMENT OF RAGE AND
CONSUMING RAGE THAT FOLLOWS A
HUMILIATING HURT.
BEING A LENER AND PROJECTED BY
OTHER PEOPLE AND JILTED BOY A
GIRLFRIEND.
FIRED FROM A JOB THINGS OF
THAT SORT AND SOMEBODY WHO HAS
LITTLE ORDINARY HUMAN
RESOURCES IN THE WAY OF
SOCIABILITY.
AND ALLOWS THEM TO SOFTEN THE
RAGE EFFORT AND MELT DOWN IN A
CHRONIC ANGER AND THEY ARE
EXPLOSIVE AND THEY EXPLODE
WITH RAGE AND GET VENGEANCE BY
COMMITTING A MURDEROUS ACT.
AND DEPETS BACK AT PEOPLE WHO
HURT THEM AND THEY DON'T CARE
IF THEY DIE IN THE PROCESS .
>> THESE KIDS DIDN'T HURT
ANYONE.
WHY GO AFTER THE CHILDREN?
>> THERE IS A CONNECTION I
SUSPECT WITH THE MOTHER WHO
WAS A TEACHER AT THAT SCHOOL
OR PART-TIME.
HE WAS UNABLE TO REALLY LIVE
PRETTY MUCH ON HIS OWN AND HE
LIVED WITH HIS MOTHER AND SHE
COLLECTED GUNS WHICH IS OUD
ODD FOR A WOMAN TO DO.
AND THERE WAS A DISPUTE.
YOU MAY NEVER KNOW WHAT KIND
OF DISPUTE THERE WAS BETWEEN
HER AND HIM.
BUT IF HE WANTS TO GET
VENGEANCE AND COMMIT MASS
MURDER, HE GOES TO THE SCHOOL
AND KILLS WHO EVER IS THERE.
CHILDREN ARE HELPLESS AND HE
CAN DO THE MOST DAMAGE AND GET
HIS HORRIBLE 15 MINUTES OF
FAME AND DYING IN THE PROCESS.
THROWING HIS LIFE AWAY IN THIS
RAGE.
AS A PERSON WHO PROBABLY
SENSED MORE AND MORE HE COULD
NEVER CONNECT WITH PEOPLE AND
HAVE A NORPAL LIFE OR FAMILY.
PARANOI UPONIA SCHIZOPHRENIA,
IS THAT A CAUSAL FACTOR.
HE IS IN THE AGE BRACKET WHERE
THAT AFFLICTION STRIKES.
>> HE'S IN THE AGE BRACKET.
BUT I DON'T SEE HIM AS
SCHIZOPHRENIA.
THE TENDENCY OF VIOLENCES IN
SCHIZOPHRENIA IS FOUR OR 6
PERCENT INSTEAD OF ONE
PERCENT.
AND WORSE IF THEY DRINK
ALCOHOL.
I SEE HIM MORE IN THE AUTISTIC
VERY HIGH INTELIENCE, AND
AUTISTIC PERSON WHO CANE HAVE
EMPATHY WITH OTHER PEOPLE AND
CAN'T UNDERSTAND THE FOALINGS
AND CAN'T MAKE MAUL TALK AND
LOOK YOU IN THE EYES.
AND REGULATED TO THE MARGINS
WAS SOCIETY BY VIRTURE OF
BEING LONERS THAT CAN'T
CONNECT.
>> THEY GET MORE ANGRY ABOUT
THAT.
>> THEY SAY HE WAS A SMART GUY
AND KIND OF A LONER AND DIDN'T
ENGAGE IN OTHER PEOPLE.
DR. MICHAEL STONE, THANK YOU
FOR SHARING YOUR EXPERTISE .
>> WE HEARD FROM MAYOR GULIANI
IT IS THE REMINDER IN THE
WORST WAY THAT EVIL EXIST IN
THE WORLD.
ON THE GROUND.
CRISIS TEEMS ARE HERE AND
HELPING THE COMMUNITY GRIEVE
AND WE GRIEVE ALONG WITH THEM.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH MORE
NEWS FROM NEWTOWN AHEAD.
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE SAID
THE GUNMAN FORCED HIS WAY IN
THE BUILDING.
THEY WILL RELEASE THE NAMES OF
THE VICTIMS POSSIBLY LATER
TODAY.
AND ANOTHER 48 HOURS OR MORE.
AND POLICE LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE IS PLEADING WITH THE
MEDIA TO PROTECT THE PRIVACY
OF THE GRIEVING FAMILIES.
GOVERNOR MIKE HUCKABEE.
IN JONESBORO COUPLE OF KIDS
OPENED FIRE ON THEIR CLASS
HEIGHTS.
NONE OF THEM WAS LEN YEARS
OLD.
>> THE OTHER WAS 12.
THEY TRICKED THEIR CLASS MATES
AND TEACHERS AND USED A FIRE
ALARM OUT OF THE CLASSROOM TO
A FENCED AREA.
THEY OPEN HAPPENED FIRE AND
THE DOORS LOCKED AND THE KIDS
COULDN'T GET BACK IN.
THEY KILLED FIVE AND WOUNDED
10.
ONE OF THE FIVE KILLED WAS A
TEACHER AND THE QUESTION IS,
HOW DO YOU DOLE WITH AN 11
YEAR OLD WHO KILLED WITH
SOMEONE?
IT NEVER OCCURRED TO ANYONE
THAT WE NEELEDED TO CENTER A
LAW THAT SAID IT WAS WRONG FOR
AN 11 YEAR OLD TO COMMIT MASS
MURDER.
>> THEY WERE HELD UNDER
ARKANSAS LAW UNDER THE AGE OF
18.
AND WOULDN'T HAVE CRIMINAL
REARS.
AFTER 21 THEY WERE FREE.
AND THE PROBLEM THAT WE OFTEN
FACE, HOW COME WE DIDN'T HAVE
A LAW.
YOU CAN'T HAVA A LAW TO
PREDICT.
WE DO HAVE A LAW.
THOU SMALT NOT KILL.
THE SPECIFIC APPLICATION IS
NEVER GOING TO BE THERE.
IF PEOPLE SAPE I HOPE WE CAN
PASS LAW.
WE CAN AND IT IS IT A REACTION
AND THEN MANAGE ELSE WILL
HAPPEN AND WE'LL SAY YET WE
HAVE MORE LAWS.
THERE IS A BIGGER ISSUE AND
THAT IS THIS WHOLE DISCUSSION
OF WHO WE ARE AS A CULTURE AND
AS A PEOPLE.
THERE IS NO SIMPLE ANSWER TO
WE'LL TALK ABOUT GUNS TO
ASBERGERS AND A WHOLE OF
THINGS THAT SHOULD BE A PART
OF THE CONVERSATION .
AND IF ANYBODY IS LOOKING FOR
MAGIB OR SIMPLE THEY ARE
LOOKING IN VAIP .
>> RUDY GULIANI SAID THERE IS
NO ONE SOLUTION .
NNO, THERE IS NOT.
>> IT IS A CULTURAL PROBLEM?
>> IT IS IT.
A LOT OF PEOPLE WILL
DISSDISMISS THAT.
AND I SAID IT EARLIER ON FOX
AND FRIENDS.
JOHN, KIDS WENT TO SCHOOL AT
MY SCHOOL AND WE HAD GUNS IN
THE VEHICLES AND GUN RACKS
VISIBLE.
AND GUNS ON THE SCHOOL PARKING
LOT.
BECAUSE PEOPLE HUNTED BEFORE
AND AFTER SCHOOL.
PART OF THE CULTURE, BUT IT
WAS NOT PART OF THE CULTURE TO
KILL EACH OTHER ON THE CAMPUS
UMP.
THE GUNS WERE THERE.
AND THE MIPPED SET HAS TO GET
INTO PLAY FOR POEM TO COMMIT
THIS OF A CRUME .
NYOU ARE ALSO APE MIN >>
Brian:ER AND WHAT DO YOU SAY
TO THE FAMILIES OF THE KIDS.
>> THERE ARE NO WORFS.
MY EXPERIENCE 30 YEARS AGO IS
A ONE.
MORE YOU HUG PEOPLE AND GET
CLOSE TO THEM AND LESS YOU SAY
AND SHED REAL TEARS WITH THEM.
WHAT THE PRESIDENT DID IN THE
PODIUM WAS THE MOST POWERFUL
THING HE COULD HAVE DONE .
HE SHED TEARS AND GO TO THE
NEW TESTAMENT, THE SHORTEST
VERSE IN ALL OF THE BIBLE.
JESUS WEPT.
AMERICA WEPT.
GOVERNOR MIKE HUCKABEE, GOOD
TO HAVE YOU AROUND AND
THARCHING YOU.
>> THANK YOU, JOHN.
>> JENNY.
>> CONTINUING COVERAGE
THROUGHOUT THE DAY IN THE DEAD
LOW SHOOTING IN SANDY HOOK
COMMUNITY.
AND COMMUNITY OF 30,000
PEOPLE.
20 FAMILIES INSURANCING THE
LOSS OF A CHILD THIS HOLIDAY
SEASON.
WE'LL BRING YOU THE LATEST ON
FOX NEWS AHEAD.
Sometimes what we suffer from
Is bigger than we think ...
like the flu.
With aches, fever and chills-
the flu's a really big deal.
So why treat it like
it's a little cold?
There's something
that works differently
than over-the-counter
remedies.
Prescription TAMIFLU attacks
the flu virus at its source.
So don't wait. Call your
doctor right away.
TAMIFLU is prescription
medicine for treating the flu
in adults and children
one year and older
whose flu symptoms started
within the last two days.
Before taking TAMIFLU tell your
doctor if you're pregnant,
nursing. have serious
health conditions,
or take other medicines.
If you develop an allergic
reaction, a severe rash,
or signs of unusual behavior,
stop taking TAMIFLU and call
your doctor immediately.
Children and adolescents in
particular may be at an
increased risk
of seizures, confusion
or abnormal behavior.
The most common
side effects are
mild to moderate nausea
and vomiting.
The flu comes on fast,
so ask your
doctor about TAMIFLU.
Prescription for flu.
>> A FOX NEWS ALERT NOW.
IN THE MIDWEST, POLICE NEED
YOUR HELP.
A MANHUNT IN MISSOURI FOR THIS
MAN.
30 YEAR OLD GARY.
WANTED FOR THE MURDER OF A
WASHINGTON COUNTY HAD
SHERIFF'S DEPUTY.
IT HAPPENED IN MINERAL
SPRINGS.
LOCAL POLICE WERE ASSISTING
THE AMBULANCE CALL WERE
AMBUSHED AND THE OFFICER
KILLED.
THE SUSPECT RAN OFF IN THE
WOODS.
HE IS 6-2 INCHES TALL.
AND WEARING CAMOUFLAGE AND
CONSIDERED ARMED AND
DANGEROUS.
THREETTHREESE POLICE ARE
SEARCHING FOR HIM.
HE IS BELIEVED TO BE ARMED.
GENA .
A DEVELOPING STORE TORE.
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
A TOWN OF 30,000 OR LESS THAN
THAT IN FACT.
SOME OF THE JOURNALGIST THAT I
AM SPEAKING WITH THAT ARE
LOCAL HERE MEPTIONED THAT NEW
TUNE IS A CENTER AND MAYBE
LOOK AT THE SCHOOL DISTRICT AS
A GREAT ONE TO CHOOSE FOR THE
CHILDREN BECAUSE IT IS IT SO
NICE.
WE'LL REFLECT ON THE SIGHTS
AND SOUNDS AS THE EVENSUB
UNNOLDED.
>> IT DOESN'T SEEM REAL .
IT DOESN'T SEEM POSSIBLE.
NIT IS NO WORDS.
>> IT IS SHEER TERROR .
AND SENSE OF URGEENCY.
AND YOU KNOW TO GET TO YOUR
CHILD AND TO BE THERE TO
PROTECT THEM.
>> THERE IMAGINE PHONE CALL
AND THE SCHOOLS ARE ON LOOK
DOWN .
I HAVE A REST THA APEER THAT
HAS WOMAN AM ON THE SCHOOL.
THERE WERE HISIR BEING AL
MISDEMEANORS AND ED WHAT WAS
GOING ON .
SHE SAID THE PRINCIPAL IS DEAD
AND THE CHILDREN CAME OUT WITH
BLOOD.
>> WE ARE COPE TRYING TO FIND
OUT WHAT IS ON.
IT IS NERVE WRACKING.
AND WE DO HAVE MORE CARS
COMING IN.
>> WE WAS IN A SMALL READING
GROUP, AND THEY TARTED
HEARINGIX BANGS, AND HER
TOACHER WHICH I AM SO GRATEFUL
FOR.
THERE WAS A SMALL DROP AND
RUSHED THID CANS IN THE BATH
ROM AND LOCKED THE DOOR.
AND THEY TOLD THE CHILDREN
THAT IT WAS HAMMERING.
AND TRIED TO CIPE THEM CALM.
THE NEXT THING I KNOW, BECAUSE
IT IS VERY HARD TO GET A
COMPLETE STORY, THE NEXT THING
I KNOW, IS THALT POLICE CAME
AND THEY WERE KNOCKING ON THE
DOOR TO BE LET OUT OF THE
CLASSROOM AND WHEN THEY WERE.
SHE HAD SEEN GLASS AND BLOOD.
ONE CHILD RECOVERED IN BLOOD
BUT THAT CHOILED IS SAFE MUCH
>> WAS TALKING ABOUT HOW THE
WALKING DOWN THE HALLWAY
PLETES TOLD THEM TO CLOSE
THEIR EYES.
IT WAS A SENSITIVE SCENE.
AND SHE SAID SHE HEARD GUN
SHOTS AND WHAT SHE TOLD ME WAS
IN THE BEGINNING.
THE INTERCOM CAME ON AND SHE
HEARD A SCREAM ON THE INTERCOM
AND IT WENT IMMEDIATELY OFF.
AND I AM NOT SURE WITH THE
SPECTACULARS AND HOW THE
SCHOOL WAS LOCKED DOWN.
SHE HEARD SCREAM AND GUN
SHOTS.
IT IS IT NOT HEADACHING SENSE.
IT IS SENSELESS.
OUR HEARTS ARE WITH EVERYBODY.
EVERYBODY PARENT AND MOTHER
AND FATHER AND GRAND MOTHER
AND MOTHER AND BROTHER AND
SISTER AND ALL OF THE OTHER
CHILDREN .
>> EVERYBODY IS DOING.
AND A COUPLE OF FRENS WEEP
HAVEN'T GROTEN IN TOUCH W. WE
HOPE EVERYTHING IS OKAY WITH
THEM.
>> YOU MIGHT HAVE HEARD THERE
WAS A DESCRIPTION OF GLASS ON
FLOOR THERE WAS GLASS ALL OVER
THE SCHOOL.
NFIVER RESPONDERS HAD TO
FIGURE OUT THEIR OWN WAY TO
FORCE THEIR WAY IN THE SCHOOL
AND MAKE SURE THES WERE
PROTECTED.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH MORE
AED HAD.
-- AHEAD.
>> ALL RIGHT.
GENA, WE ARE LOOKING FOR
ANSWERS AS TO WHAT HAPPENED.
WE'LL HEAR MORE FROM THE STATE
POLICE.
THEY PROMISED A NEW'S
CONFERENCE.
IF IT TAKES PLACE WE'LL HAVE
IT HERE LIVE ON FOX.
This is how Mommy learned...
...and now...
You!
[ giggles ]
♪ The one and only, Cheerios
It's hard to see opportunity
in today's challenging
environment.
Unless you have the right
perspective.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
has the vision
and experience to look beyond
the obvious.
We'll uncover opportunities,
find hidden risk,