>> TONIGHT, WE'RE COMING TO YOU
LIVE FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WHICH JUST YESTERDAY WAS A SCENE
OF UNIMAGINABLE HORROR AND
GRIEF.
TODAY A COMMUNITY AND A NATION
TRY TO MAKE SENSE OF THE
INCOMPREHENSIBLE.
THE SENSELESS KILLING OF
STUDENTS AND THEIR TEACHERS.
WE NOW KNOW THE NAMES OF ALL 20
CHILDREN, MURDERED IN THEIR OWN
CLASSROOMS, THAT PLACE WHICH
SHOULD BE A HAVEN OF SAFETY IN A
HEARTLESS WORLD.
THEIR NAMES SO MUCH LIKE THE
NAMES OF CHILDREN WE ALL KNOW.
12 GIRLS AND EIGHT BOYS.
CHARLOTTE, AND DYLAN, JESSE, AND
EMILY.
TO NAME JUST A FEW.
AND JUST A LITTLE WHILE AGO, WE
HEARD FROM ROBBY PARKER, THE
FATHER OF SIX-YEAR-OLD EMILY.
ONE OF THE VICTIMS SHOT AND
KILLED YESTERDAY, ALONG WITH 19
OF HER LITTLE CLASSMATES.
>> FIRST OF ALL, I WOULD REALLY
LIKE TO OFFER OUR DEEPEST CON
DOLE LENSES TO ALL FAMILIES
DIRECTLY AFFECTED BY THIS
SHOOTING.
WE WANT EVERYBODY TO KNOW THAT
OUR HEARTS AND OUR PRAYERS GO
OUT TO THEM.
>> WE'RE ALSO HEARING STORIES OF
CHILDREN WHO HELPED THEIR
CLASSMATES ESCAPE.
OF THE SCHOOL PRINCIPAL WHO
RUSHED THE GUNMAN AND AN EFFORT
TO PROTECT HER SCHOOL.
OF THE TEACHER WHO PUT HERSELF
IN BETWEEN HERE STUDENTS AND THE
GUNMAN TO PROTECT HER STUDENTS.
BOTH LOSING THEIR LIVES.
AND TONIGHT WE'RE LEARNING MORE
ABOUT THE EVIL, MORE
APPROPRIATELY, THE DEVIL WHO
TORE THROUGH THAT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
HELLO, AND WELCOME TO THIS
SPECIAL EDITION OF JUSTICE.
WE ARE LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AND I'M JUDGE
JEANINE PIRRO.
THE POLICE DISPATCH AUDIO TELLS
A CHILLING STORY AS FIRST
RESPONDERS HEAR OF THE CARNAGE
TAKING PLACE AS AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL...
>> THE MEDICAL EXAMINER,
DR. WAYNE CAR VERY, HELD A PRESS
CONFERENCE, GIVING US HORRIFYING
INSIGHT INTO WHAT HAPPENED AT
THE SCHOOL AND THOSE LAST
MOMENTS.
MOLLIE WAS AT THE PRESS
CONFERENCE.
>> IN THE MEDICAL EXAMINER
RELEASED A A LOT OF DETAILS AND
SPEAK WITH CLARITY JUST HOW
HORRIBLE THIS SITUATION WAS.
HE ESSENTIALLY MADE VERY CLEAR
THAT THE VICTIMS SUFFERED
MULTIPLE GUNSHOT WOUNDS AT THE
HANDS OF A LONG GUN, RIFLE, HE
CLARIFY, WHEN HE WAS ASKED TO
CLARIFY.
WE KNOW HE PARTICIPATED IN A
NUMBER OF THOSE EXAMS HIMSELF OF
THE VICTIMS, OF THESE LOVED
ONES, AND OF THOSE HE EXAMINED
THAT'S SUFFERED THREE TO 11
GUNSHOT WOUNDS, AND WE'RE
TALKING ABOUT SUCH LITTLE
CHILDREN, THE YOUNGEST VICTIM,
SIX YEARS OLD, A BOY NAMED NOAH,
TINY, TINY PEOPLE THAT WERE
DESPERATELY TRYING TO SAVE THEIR
OWN LIVES, AND THESE WOMEN, SIX
WOMEN, GUNNED DOWN THAT WERE
TRYING TO SAVE THE CHILDREN.
>> WHAT WAS INTERESTING IN THAT
PRESS CONFERENCE, ALSO THE FACT
HE SAID, ALTHOUGH HE IS THE
CHIEF MEDICAL EXAMINER THIS IS
THE WORST HE HAS EVER SEEN.
>> HE SAID HE WORKED A THIRD OF
A CENTURY IN HIS LIFE DOING
MEDICAL EXAMS.
THIS IS THE WORST AND ALL OF HIS
COLLEAGUES HAVE SEASON.
SO HEARING ABOUT IT, WHAT WE
HAVE SEEN HERE ON THE SCENE, THE
EMOTION OF THE COMMUNITY, HE HAS
PHYSICALLY SEEP IT HIMSELF.
THEY ASKED HIM IF HE HAD CRIED
AND HE SAID SO FAR HE HASN'T,
BUT HE SAID SO FAR HE HASN'T.
>> CLEARLY, A BIG ISSUE WILL BE
THE EMOTIONAL RESPONSE BY ALL
THESE FIRST RESPONDERS, POLICE,
AND EVERYONE ELSE.
MOLLY, WE HEAR THE PRESIDENT IS
COMING INTO TOWN TOMORROW.
>> THE DETAILS HAVE NOT BEEN
NAILED DOWN BUT PRESIDENT OBAMA
IS EXPECTED TO MAKE A VISIT TO
THE TOWNSHIP, TO ATTEND AN ENTER
FAITH VILLAGE TOLL PULL TOGETHER
THE COMMUNITY.
THERE HAVE BEEN SO MANY VIGILS
HELD ACROSS THE COMMUNITY SINCE
THE MASSACRE OCCURRED, EVERYONE
PULLING TOGETHER.
THE NEWTOWN HAS PULLED TOWN, AND
THE SURROUNDING COMMUNITY, AND
THIS SHOWS THE ENTIRE COUNTRIES
INVOLVED IN WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
THIS IS A MUCH BIGGER TRAGEDY
NORTH JUST NEWTOWN, NOT JUST
CONNECTICUT.
>> MOLLY, THANKS SO MUCH.
MOLLY WILL BE ON THE SCENE HERE
TOMORROW, CONTINUING WITH HER
COVERAGE, AND NOW TO MIKE TOBIN
WITH REACTION FROM THE PEOPLE OF
THE TOWN.
>> THE PAIN OF THIS TRAGEDY IS
REFRESHED BECAUSE WE'RE LEARNING
THE NAMES AND FACES OF THE
SMALLEST VICTIMS OF THIS
UNSPEAKABLE TRAGEDY.
NAMES LIKE GRACE McDONALD,
WHOSE FAMILY SAID SHE WAS THE
LOVE AND LIFE OF THE FAMILY.
SIX-YEAR-OLD EMILY PARKER WHO
SAID GOODBYE TO HER FATHER
BEFORE HE WENT OFF TO WORK.
>> SHE WOKE UP AS I LEFT.
AND I'VE BEEN TEACHING HER
PORTUGUESE, AND OUR LAUGHS
CONVERSATION WAS IN PORTUGUESE,
AND SHE TOLD ME GOOD MORNING,
AND ASKED HOW I WAS DOING, I
SAID I WAS DOING WELL.
SHE SAID SHE LOVED ME, AND I
GAVE HER A KISS AND WALKED OUT
THE DOOR.
>> SADLY FAMILIAR, THE MAKESHIFT
MEMORIALS ARE POPPING UP AROUND
TOWN, WITH CANDLES, TOYS,
FLOWERS LAID OUT.
THE PEOPLE HERE ARE DRAWING ON
THE BONDS FORGED IN A SMALL TOWN
SO THEY CAN SOMEHOW ENDURE THIS
SADNESS.
>> I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
NEVER BEEN FACED WITH SOMETHING
OF THIS MAGNITUDE.
OUR FOCUS IS, AGAIN -- WE HAVE
ENOUGH TIME DEALING WITH IT,
PROCESSING ALL THE INFORMATION.
TRY TO GET THROUGH THIS.
>> JUDGE, YOU MAY NOTICE THE
FLAG POLE IN THE CENTER OF TOWN,
THE FLAG IS AT HALF STAFF BUT
THEY'RE SOMETHING MISSING AND
THAT IS CHRISTMAS DECORATIONS, A
LOT OF PEOPLE HERE FELT IT
WASN'T APPROPRIATE TO CELEBRATE
IN THE FACE OF ALL THE TRAGEDY
AND VOLUNTARILY TOOK THE
CHRISTMAS DECORATIONS DOWN.
BACK TO YOU.
>> HOW SAD.
MIKE TO BENN, THANK SO MUCH.
WITH US ON THE PHONE IS ROBERT
LA COTA, WHOSE SIX-YEAR-OLD SON
ADEN WAS IN SCHOOLEND.
HE ACTUALLY WITNESSED THE
SHOOTING OF HIS TEACHER, VICKY
SOTO.
ROBERT, ARE YOU THERE?
>> YES.
>> ALL RIGHT.
ROBERT.
THANKS SO MUCH FOR BEING WITH
US.
TELL US ABOUT YOUR SIX-YEAR-OLD.
WHAT DID HE SEE?
WHAT DID HE TELL YOU?
>> UM, WELL, HE DID HEAR NOISES
OUTSIDE THE CLASSROOM, THEY ALL
DID.
AND AT THAT POINT HIS TEACHER,
VICKY SOTO, WHO IS A HERO IN ALL
OF OUR MINDS, A WONDERFUL
TEACHER, AND PERSON -- HAD THE
PRESENCE OF MIND TO MAKE SURE
THE CHILDREN WERE IN A
RELATIVELY SAFE AREA OF THE ROOM
AWAY FROM THE ENTRANCE OF THE
CLASSROOM, AND THEY WERE
WAITING, AND WAITING FOR SOMEONE
TO COME, AND AT THAT POINT THE
GUNMAN BURST INTO THE ROOM, AND
SHOT VICKY SOTO, AND THAT'S WHEN
MORE SHOTS WERE FIRED.
>> SO SHE WAS ACTUALLY SHOT IN
FRONT OF YOUR SIX-YEAR-OLD SON?
HE SAW THE SHOOTING?
>> CORRECT, YES, HE DID.
>> AND WHAT IS HE TELLING YOU
NOW, ROBERT, ABOUT HOW HE IS
FEELING AND HOW ARE YOU DEALING
WITH THIS?
>> UM, HE -- WE'RE TRYING TO
KEEP A NORMAL ROUTINE.
WE'RE TRYING TO GET HIM -- STILL
BRUSH HIS TEETH AND GO TO BED AT
A REASONABLE TIME.
BUT HE DOES ASK QUESTIONS ABOUT
THE BAD PERSON, AND YESTERDAY
WAS PARTICULARLY DIFFICULT.
HE WAS TEARFUL EVEN GOING HOME
AFTER WE LEFT THE POLICE
STATION.
HE IS GETTING BETTER, BUT HE IS
STILL AFRAID OF DEATH.
>> ROBERT, I UNDERSTAND YOU ALSO
HAVE A SEVEN-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER
NAMED KALIN WHO WAS IN THE
CAFETERIA AND ACTUALLY IN
LEAVING THE SCHOOL, SAW THE
BODIES OF THESE CHILDREN?
>> HER CLASSROOM WAS NEAR THE
CAFETERIA.
SHE WAS IN HER ROOM WITH HER
TEACHER AND FELLOW STUDENTS, IN
A DIFFERENT SECTION OF THE
BUILDING.
BUT SHE DID, AS I'M SURE MANY OF
THE CHILDREN DID, BEAR WITNESS
TO VERY HORRIFIC THINGS.
YES, SHE DID SEE SOME BODIES,
YES.
>> OH, AND FINALLY, I UNDERSTAND
THAT YOUR SON UNDERSTANDABLY,
ADEN, WHO SAW HIS TEACHER BEING
SHOT, IS RELUCTANT TO BE
SEPARATED FROM THE FAMILY OR
FROM YOU.
I IMAGINE THAT THAT'S NOT
SURPRISING.
>> YEAH.
SO WE'RE GOING -- WE'RE GETTING
THROUGH THIS WITH THE HELP AND
LOVE AND SUPPORT OF OUR FRIENDS,
OUR FAMILY, OUR NEIGHBORS, AND
WE'RE STAYING CLOSE.
THAT DOESN'T MEAN -- TODAY HE
DID HAVE A PLAY DATE WITH A GOOD
FRIEND OF HIS.
AT HIS FRIEND'S HOUSE.
SO AS LONG AS HE IS SOMEWHERE
WHERE HE FEELS SAFE, IT'S A GOOD
THING.
BUT MORE OFTEN THAN NOT HE WANTS
TO KNOW WHETHER WE'RE CLOSE BY
AND WANTS TO STAY IN FAMILIAR
PLACES.
>> CERTAINLY UNDERSTANDABLE.
ROBERT, THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
SHARING THIS WITH US AND ALL ENU
THIS EVENING.
AND TO YOUR SON AS WELL.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> NOW I'M JOINED ON THE PHONE
BY STEVEN, WHOSE DAUGHTER
DESCRIBED TO HIM WHAT SHE HEARD
OVER THE LOUD SPEAKER FROM THE
PRINCIPAL'S OFFICE WHEN THE
SHOOTING BEGAN.
ARE YOU THERE, STEVEN?
>> YES, HI.
>> THANKS SO MUCH FOR BEING WITH
US.
I AM WELL.
HOW ARE YOU?
HOW IS YOUR EIGHT-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHTER?
>> SHE IS DOING PRETTY GOOD.
SAMANTHA IS A STRONG-WILLED
CHILD, THANK GOD, AND AT THIS
MOMENT WE'RE BOTH BLESSED, MY
WHOLE FAMILY HAS BEEN BLESSED,
THAT SHE CAME OUT OF THIS THING
PHYSICALLY OKAY.
BUT NATURALLY VERY ROTTEN
SITUATION TO BE INVOLVED IN.
IT'S BEEN VERY ROCKY.
>> STEVE --
>> GETTING BETTER.
>>  -- WHAT DID SHE SAY SHE
HEARD?
>> WHAT HAPPENED.
SHE WAS IN MRS. MARTIN'S CLASS,
AND THEY UNFORTUNATELY IN THEIR
CLASSROOM DON'T HAVE A BATHROOM
OR ANY MEANS OF HIDING OR
ESCAPING IN ANY CABINETS OR
ANYTHING.
SO THEY WERE IN THE CLASS, AND
IT SEEMS THAT ONE,
UNFORTUNATELY, DID TRIP THE LOUD
SPEAKER SYSTEM, AND SHE HEARD
CURSING COMING FROM THE LOUD
SPEAKER.
AND KIND OF LOOKED AROUND AND
THEN THEY HEARD -- SHE HEARD TWO
LARGE BOOM NOISES, AND THAT'S
WHEN MISS MARTIN WAS --
FABULOUS.
BASICALLY GOT THE KIDS IN THE
CORNER AND MADE THEM REMAIN
THERE QUIETLY, AND THEY JUST
WAITED IT OUT UNTIL THE POLICE
CAME.
>> STEVEN, THIS WHOLE
CIRCUMSTANCE, THIS WHOLE
SITUATION, WHEN DID YOU HEAR
ABOUT IT?
WHAT IS THE FIRST THING YOU
HEARD AND WHAT WERE YOUR FIRST
THOUGHTS?
>> THE TOWN IS -- AS EVERYBODY
HAS HEARD, ACROSS THE COUNTRY
AND THE WORLD, THE TOWN IS JUST
A GREAT, GREAT TOWN, AND WHAT
MOST AMERICANS DON'T UNDERSTAND
IS SOMETHING LIKE THAT'S
OBVIOUSLY NEVER HAPPENS,
ESPECIALLY IN OUR TOWN.
SO THEY NEED TO BE AWARE, BUT
BASICALLY WE HAVE A REVERSE
9-1-1 SYSTEM WHICH CALLS ALL THE
PARENTS IN ANY EVENT THAT
HAPPENS, AND IF YOU SEE THAT,
AND I FIRST HEARD THERE WAS A
POSSIBLE SHOOTING, AND SO WHAT
IS RUNNING THROUGH YOUR MIND,
OBVIOUSLY, YOUR MIND JUST RACES
AND YOUR ADRENALINE JUST GOES
RIGHT TO YOUR HEAD.
SO BASICALLY I WAS AT MY OFFICE?
NEW YORK, AND OBVIOUSLY DROVE
TOWARDS NEWTOWN, AND ONE OF MY
FELLOW FATHERS -- FRIENDS, FRANK
DeMAYO, CALLED ME AND ACTUALLY
LOCATING OUR CHILDREN FOR US.
SO I HAD A SENSE OF RELIEF
BEFORE I ACTUALLY GOT THERE, BUT
UNTIL I ACTUALLY SAW HER FACE, I
WASN'T SATISFIED.
>> ALL RIGHT.
SO, STEPHEN, THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR SHARING THIS WITH US AND ALL
OUR LOVE GOES OUT TO YOU AND
YOUR FAMILY AS WELL.
>> THANK YOU.
>> COMING UP, THE AMAZING
STORIES FROM INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
A TEACHER TELLS US ABOUT THE
STUDENT THAT HE LOST.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
IT STARTED LONG AGO.
THE JOY OF GIVING SOMETHING
EVERYTHING YOU'VE GOT.
IT TAKES PASSION.
AND IT'S NOT LETTING UP
ANYTIME SOON.
AT UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company,
WE UNDERSTAND THAT COMMITMENT.
AND ALWAYS HAVE.
SO DOES AARP,
AN ORGANIZATION
SERVING THE NEEDS
OF AMERICANS 50 AND OVER
FOR GENERATIONS.
SO IT'S NO SURPRISE
MILLIONS HAVE CHOSEN
AN AARP Medicare Supplement
Insurance Plan,
INSURED BY UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company.
LIKE ALL STANDARDIZED
MEDICARE SUPPLEMENT PLANS,
THEY HELP COVER
SOME OF THE EXPENSES
MEDICARE DOESN'T PAY.
AND SAVE YOU UP TO THOUSANDS
IN OUT-OF-POCKET COSTS.
TO FIND OUT MORE,
REQUEST YOUR
FREE DECISION GUIDE.
CALL OR GO ONLINE TODAY.
AFTER ALL,
WHEN YOU'RE GOING THE DISTANCE,
IT'S NICE TO HAVE
THE EXPERIENCE AND COMMITMENT
TO GO ALONG WITH YOU.
KEEP DREAMING. KEEP DOING.
GO LONG.
>> EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY
TODAY.
>> A CALL CAME INTO DISPATCH,
POLICE OFFICERS AND RESOURCES
FROM ALL OVER THE STATE RACED
TO THAT AREA AS THEY CONVERGED
ON THE SCHOOL.
>> THE CHILDREN OBVIOUSLY WERE
VERY SHAKEN.
THEY WERE CRYING IN THE
CLOSET.
WHEN THEY WERE LEAVING, THE
POLICE MADE THEM HOLD HANDS
AND TOLD THEM TO CLOSE THEIR
EYES.
>> THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS.
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
>> MY GYM TEACHER DIRECTED US
TO STAY AGAINST THE WALL.
EVERYBODY STARTED KIND OF
PANICKING.
>> THERE IS NO WORDS.
IT'S SHEAR TERROR.
>> DOESN'T EVEN SEEM REAL.
IT JUST DOES NOT SEEM LIKE
IT'S EVEN POSSIBLE.
>> WE ALL HUDDLED AND I KEPT
HEARING THESE BOOMING NOISES.
[SIREN]
>> I JUST ALL OF US MOMS
NETWORKING TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT WHAT'S GOING ON.
>> KIDS WERE TERRIFIED.
THEY WERE TERRIFIED.
THEY HAD JUST WITNESSED
SOMETHING AND THEY WERE
TERRIFIED.
>> MOST TRAUMATIZING THING I
HAVE EVER BEEN THROUGH.
>> MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF
THE VICTIMS AND IN THE WORDS
OF STRICTER HEAL THE BROKEN
HEARTED AND BIND UP THEIR
WOUNDS.
>> Judge Jeanine: RAY HORVATH
IS THE HEAD TEACHER FOR THE
SCHOOL AGE PROGRAM FOR THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
FOUR, FOUR OF HIS STUDENTS
WERE KILLED YESTERDAY.
RAY HIMSELF HAD LEFT THE
SCHOOL JUST MINUTES BEFORE THE
BLOOD SHED.
HE JOINS ME NOW ON THE PHONE.
RAY?
>> YEP?
>> ARE YOU THERE, RAY?
>> YES, I AM.
>> THANKS SO MUCH FOR BEING
WITH US THIS EVENING.
TELL US ABOUT THIS PROGRAM
THAT YOU RUB.
WHAT IS THE SCHOOL AGE
PROGRAM?
>> IT PROVIDES A SERVICE TO
THE PARENTS.
PARENTS WHO HAVE TO DROP KIDS
OFF EARLY.
OBVIOUSLY YOU DON'T HAVE
BABYSITTERS AT 7:00 IN THE
MORNING.
PARENTS WHO COME HOME LATE AT
NIGHT NEED TO PARK THEIR KIDS
SOMEWHERE.
SO WE PROVIDE TUTORING, WE
HELP THEM WITH THEIR HOMEWORK.
WE PROVIDE, THERE IS IS
VARIOUS COMPONENTS TO IT
LITERACY COMPONENT ARTS AND
CRAFTS.
WE FILL UP THERE BEFORE AND
AFTER SCHOOL HOURS.
>> ALL RIGHT.
SO THEN YESTERDAY MORNING, YOU
WERE WITH THESE KIDS IN THE
PROGRAM WHOSE PARENTS DROPPED
THEM OFF AT SCHOOL BEFORE
SCHOOL STARTS.
AND YOU LEFT BEFORE THE
SHOOTING STARTED.
WERE YOU AT ALL FAMILIAR WITH
THE SHOOTER, I MEAN HAD YOU
EVEN HEARD HIS NAME BEFORE?
>> I'M SORRY, I JUST.
>> Judge Jeanine: YOU NEVER
HEARD OF HIM.
>> I DON'T THINK ANYONE IN
TOWN IS QUITE FAMILIAR.
NOW SEARCH FAMILIAR WITH HIM.
>> Judge Jeanine: ALL RIGHT.
RAY, LET ME GO RIGHT TO THE
FOUR STUDENTS THAT WERE KILLED
OF YOURS.
DID YOU SEE THEM YESTERDAY
MORNING?
WHAT WAS YESTERDAY LIKE AT
SCHOOL?
>> VERY ORDINARY DAY, VERY
ORDINARY.
A LOT OF FUN.
I LOVE KIDS.
WE HAVE A LOT OF FUN WITH
THEM.
YEAH, I THINK ALL FOUR WERE
WITH US YESTERDAY MORNING.
[CLEARING THROAT]
>> I'M SORRY, IT'S STILL
PRETTY FRESH.
SO I GET A LITTLE CHOKED UP.
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> Judge Jeanine: OF COURSE
YOU DO.
RAY, VERY QUICKLY WE'RE COMING
UP ON HARD BREAK HERE.
IT WAS NORMAL DAY FOR THE
FOUR?
>> YEAH.
SENT THEM OFF.
ONCE THE BUSES ARRIVED, WE
TRANSFER THEM WE SEND THEM OUT
OF THE ROOM AND TO THEIR
CLASSROOMS.
THEY JOIN THE CROWD COMING.
IN AND WE STAYED, WE USUALLY
GET OUT AT 9, I MEAN 9:15,
9:20.
WE STAYED A LITTLE LATE.
YOU KNOW.
>>
>> RAY, THANKS SO MUCH FOR
BEING WITH US THIS EVENING.
>>
>> YOU ARE WELCOME.
>> Judge Jeanine: HOW THE
KILLER GOT INTO THE SCHOOL.
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
INTRODUCING CHASE LIQUID.
CARD HASSLES?
THE RELOADABLE CARD
THAT'S EASY TO ACTIVATE
AND CAN BE USED RIGHT AWAY.
PLUS, YOU CAN LOAD
CASH OR CHECKS
AT ANY CHASE
DEPOSITFRIENDLY ATM
AND CHECKS RIGHT FROM
YOUR SMARTPHONE.
GET RID OF PREPAID PROBLEMS.
GET CHASE LIQUID.
>> WE HAVE ESTABLISHED THE
POINT OF ENTRY.
I CAN TELL YOU IT HE WAS NOT
VOLUNTARILY LET INTO THE
SCHOOL AT ALL.
THAT HE FORCED HIS WAY INTO
THE SCHOOL.
THAT'S AS FAR AS WE CAN GO ON
THAT.
>> Judge Jeanine: YESTERDAY'S
MASSACRE WAS JUST THE LATEST
INCIDENT OF SCHOOL VIOLENCE
THAT WE HAVE SEEN IN THIS
COUNTRY.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
HAD SAFETY MEASURES IN PLACE,
BUT THE SHOOTER WAS STILL ABLE
TO GAIN ENTRY WHICH RAISES THE
QUESTION HOW SAFE ARE OUR
SCHOOLS AND HOW SAFE ARE OUR
CHILDREN?
WITH ME IS FAIRFIELD COUNTY
POLICE CHIEF GARY MCNAMARA.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US.
>> THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
>> YOU ARE A POLICE CHIEF JUST
30 MILES FROM HERE.
>> JUST A LITTLE SOUTH OF
NEWTOWN, YEAH.
>>
>> Judge Jeanine: YOU ARE
FAMILIAR WITH THE ISSUE OF
SCHOOL VIOLENCE AND SCHOOL
SAFETY IN CONNECTICUT.
>> I AM.
>> CONNECTICUT IS A SMALL
STATE.
SO YOU KNOW THE CHIEFS OF
POLICE IN THE AREA REALLY GET
TOGETHER.
SO ANY TIME ANYTHING HAPPENS
WE REALLY DO COME TOGETHER AND
DISSECT IT TOGETHER.
>> Judge Jeanine: CHIEF, WHAT
IS MANDATED.
IS CONNECTICUT, IS THERE
ANYTHING THAT'S REQUIRED OF
THIS STATE?
>> THERE IS, ALL SCHOOLS HAVE
TO HAVE A CRISIS PLAN IN
PLACE.
AND THEN EVERY THREE MONTHS
AFTER COLUMBINE HIGH SCHOOL IN
2000, THEY HAVE TO -- EVERY
THREE MONTHS PUT THAT PLAN
INTO PLACE.
THE SCHOOL SUPERINTENDENT, THE
SCHOOL ADMINISTRATORS HAVE TO
WORK WITH LOCAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT EVERY THREE
MONTHS.
SORT OF LIKE A FIRE DRILL TO
IMPLEMENT THE PLAN TO ENSURE
--
>> -- I UNDERSTAND THAT THESE
CHILDREN ACTUALLY HAD GONE
THROUGH SOME OF THE FIRE
DRILLS AND THEY HAD DONE THAT.
BUT THE ISSUE OF SAFETY AND
THE THREAT ASSESSMENT, I MEAN,
DOES THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT
MANDATE THAT EVERY SCHOOL HAVE
A THREAT ASSESSMENT DONE
REGARDING SAFETY?
>> WELL, I THINK THERE IS SOME
SORT OF A MANDATE.
AND I'M NOT REALLY FAMILIAR
WITH HOW HEAVY THAT MANDATE
IS.
BUT I THINK GIVEN THE
ATMOSPHERE.
IT'S A PUBLIC MANDATE.
YOU HAVE TO HAVE A THREAT
ASSESSMENT IN EACH SCHOOL.
>> Judge Jeanine: WHO DECIDES,
CHIEF, HOW MUCH SAFETY IS
IMPLEMENTED AT A PARTICULAR
SCHOOL.
>> I THINK IT DEPENDS ON THE
SCHOOL DISTRICT.
IT DEPENDS ON THE LAW
ENFORCEMENT AND THE DESIGN OF
THE SCHOOL.
HOW OLD THE SCHOOLS ARE.
>> Judge Jeanine: IT'S REALLY
THE LOCALS WHO DECIDE THIS?
>> IT COMES DOWN FROM THE
STATE.
SCHOOL DISTRICTS CAN GO TO THE
STATE POLICE AND GO TO THE
STATE FOR THREAT ASSESSMENT.
>> Judge Jeanine: ALL RIGHT.
AND FINALLY THIS IS NOT THE
FIRST TIME THAT THIS STATE HAS
DEALT WITH THE ISSUE OF SCHOOL
VIOLENCE.
>> IT HAS NOT.
WE HAVE EXPERIENCED SOMETHING
IN FAIRFIELD BACK IN 2002, A
CLASSROOM FULL OF STUDENTS
HELD HOSTAGE FOR A PERIOD OF 8
HOURS.
THANKFULLY NOBODY WAS INJURED
AS THE CASE HERE.
IT TOUCHES ALL OF US.
CONNECTICUT IS A SMALL STATE.
WE ARE ALL HERE HELPING
TOGETHER.
>> Judge Jeanine: UNFORTUNATELY
WE HAD MANY DIE IN JUST OVER
THE WOODS BEHIND ME RIGHT NOW.
CHIEF, FINALLY, VERY QUICKLY,
DO YOU THINK THAT THIS COULD
HAVE BEEN PREVENTED?
>> YOU KNOW, GIVEN THE MINIMUM
FACTS I HAVE, I DON'T THINK IT
COULD HAVE BEEN PREVENTED.
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> I THINK WE HAVE SAVED A LOT
MORE KIDS THAN WOULD HAVE BEEN
DONE IF THERE WERE NO PLANS IN
PLACE.
>> I THINK WE HAVE GOT TO WORK
A LITTLE HARDER THOUGH.
CHIEF MCNAMARA THANK YOU FOR
BEING WITH US THIS EVENING.
>> THANK YOU.
>> COMING UP:  WHO WAS THIS
SHOOTER WHO LITERALLY
UNLEASHED HELL AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
COMING UP INSIDE THE MIND OF A
KILLER.
There is no
mass-produced human.
Every human being
is unique.
And there is one store
that recognizes it.
The Sleep Nuer Store.
The only place in the
world you'll find the
extraordinarily comfortable
Sleep Number Experience.
An exclusive collection of
innovations that totally
individualize your sleep.
Perfectly comfortable
pillows that adjust to
your size and shape.
Temperature-balancing
bedding.
Dual warmth comforters.
All designed around the
Sleep Number Bed: A bed
with dual-air technology
that allows you to adjust
to the support your
body needs.
Each of your bodies.
In the name of human
individuality: The Sleep
Number Collection.
Discover how our sleep
professionals can
individualize your sleep
experience.
Exclusively at one of our 400
Sleep Number Stores nationwide.
eep Number.
Comfort Individualized.
This holiday season, give
the gift that's magical:
the innovative AirFit
adjustable pillow at
special 30% savings.
HE LOVES RISK.
BUT WHETHER
HE'S CLIMBING EVEREST,
SCUBA DIVING THE
GREAT BARRIER REEF WITH SHARKS,
OR JUMPING INTO THE MARKET,
HE GOES WITH PEOPLE HE TRUSTS,
WHICH IS WHY HE TRADES
WITH A COMPANY
THAT DOESN'T NICKEL AND DIME
HIM WITH HIDDEN FEES.
SO HE CAN WORRY
ABOUT OTHER THINGS,
LIKE WHAT THE MARKET IS DOING
AND BEING READY,
NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENS,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE,
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
>> HE WAS DIFFERENT, HE WAS
QUIET.
NICE KID.
GOOD KID.
I MEAN, HE WAS DEFINITELY
CHALLENGE THE FAMILY IN THAT
HOUSE.
EVERY FAMILY HAS ONE.
I HAVE ONE.
THEY HAVE ONE.
BUT NEVER IN TROUBLE WITH THE
LAW.
NEVER IN TROUBLE WITH
ANYTHING.
I KNOW SHE HAD ISSUES WITH
SCHOOL.
SHE EVENTUALLY WOUND UP HOME
SCHOOLING HIM.
SHE BATTLED WITH THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT.
IN WHAT CAPACITY I'M NOT 100%
CERTAIN IF IT WAS BEHAVIOR OR
LEARNING DISABILITIES, I
REALLY DON'T KNOW BUT IS HE A
VERY VERY BRIGHT BOY.
HE IS SMART.
>> Judge Jeanine: IT DOESN'T
MAKE SENSE.
A LOT OF QUESTIONS ABOUT THE
SHOOTER.
BUT I HAVE TO TELL YOU MY
BACKGROUND, I'M REALLY NOT SO
INTERESTED IN THE MENTAL STATE
OF THE SHOOTER.
I'M INTERESTED IN THE VICTIM.
I'M INTERESTED IN THE PEOPLE
WHO NEVER CHOSE TO BE A VICTIM
IN THE FIRST PLACE AS OPPOSED
TO GUY WHO MAKES A A DECISION
TO DRESS UP IN BLACK GARB AND
A MILITARY VEST AND TAKE A
LONG GUN AND TWO
SEMIAUTOMATICS AND COME INTO
THE SCHOOL WHERE THE MOST
VULNERABLE VICTIMS IN OUR
SOCIETY ARE AND TAKE THEIR
LIVES.
TO ME, THE ISSUE OF THE STATE
OF MIND OF THE CRIMINAL IS NOT
SO MUCH ABOUT HIS STATE OF
MIND BUT ABOUT HIS CHOICE.
HE IS THE ONE WHO CHOSE TO
PICK UP A GUN.
MAKE A DECISION TO KILL.
BUT HAVING SAID THAT, MY
PROSECUTOR BACKGROUND I WILL
NOW PUT ON HOLD AND I WILL ASK
AND FIRST OF ALL INTRODUCE
DR. JOHN SHARP, WHO IS A
PSYCHIATRIST ON THE FACULTY OF
THE HARVARD MEDICAL SCHOOL,
DR. SHARP, SO GOOD TO HAVE YOU
HERE.
YOU HEARD ME RAMP, I DON'T
MUCH CARE ABOUT THIS GUY'S
STATE OF MIND.
I CARE ABOUT THE VICTIMS.
THE VICTIM'S FAMILY THE RIPPLE
EFFECT.
THE FACT THAT THIS TOWN WILL
FOREVER BEAR THE INSIGNIFICANT
ANY I CAN'T INSIGNIA THAT
HAPPENS HERE.
>> LET'S TALK ABOUT GRIEVING
AND.
>> I'M A PARENT.
I DROP THEM OFF AT THAT SCHOOL
BECAUSE I THOUGHT THEY WOULD
LEARN TO BE SAFE.
WHAT AM I FEELING RIGHT NOW?
>> YOU ARE FEELING ANGRY.
YOU ARE FEELING SCARED.
YOU ARE FEELING SO MANY
DIFFERENT EMOTIONS IT'S HARD
TO KEEP THEM STRAIGHT.
EVERYONE WOKE UP TODAY TO THE
WORST NIGHTMARE TO EVEN
IMAGINE THAN WHEN THEY WENT TO
BED LAST NIGHT.
WHAT PARENTS HAVE TO DO IS
PROVIDE A SENSE OF SAFETY FOR
THEIR CHILDREN.
>> Judge Jeanine: BUT THEY
DIDN'T.
DO THEY LIVE WITH GUILT?
HOW DO THEY RESOLVE WHAT THEY
HAVE GONE THROUGH?
HOW DO THEY PROTECT THEIR OWN
CHILDREN.
>> WHAT WE KNOW TWO DIFFERENT
THINGS.
THAT DOESN'T MAKE US FEEL
BETTER OR SAFE WHEN WE
CONSIDER DROPPING OUR KID
SOMEWHERE OR GOING TO A MALL.
WE HAVE TO REMEMBER THAT WE
CAN SUPPORT ONE ANOTHER AND
RECREATE A SENSE OF SAFETY.
AND MAKE SURE THE KIDS FEEL
THAT WAIT A MINUTE KIDS CAN BE
MORE RESILIENT THAN ADULTS
EVEN.
>> Judge Jeanine: I HE AGREE KIS
ARE MORE RESILIENT.
WE JUST SPOKE WITH A FATHER
WHOSE 6-YEAR-OLD IS AFRAID TO
HAVE HIM LEAVE HIM SIDE.
>> THAT'S A NORMAL RESPONSE.
RESPOND TO WHAT YOU ARE SEEING
IN YOUR CHILDREN.
IT'S DIFFERENT IF YOU ARE
TALKING TO A 6-YEAR-OLD OR A
PRETEEN OR TEEN.
6-YEAR-OLD IS VERY CONCRETE.
YOU WANT TO SEE THOUSAND THEY
ARE FEELING.
MAKE SURE THEY FEEL SAFE.
OBSERVE THEM AND COMFORT THEM.
PRETEENS GET CAUGHT UP IN
MORALITY.
VERY BLACK AND WHITE.
MAKE SURE THEY ARE THINKING
RIGHT.
>> Judge Jeanine: WHAT ABOUT
THE KIDS WHO ARE WATCHING
TELEVISION AND SHOULD PARENTS
TAKE ADVANTAGE OF THIS
SITUATION TO TALK TO THEIR
CHILDREN AND SAY THIS IS WHAT
YOU SHOULD DO OR THIS IS, YOU
KNOW, WHAT HAPPENS IN THE
WORLD?
>> ESPECIALLY THEY ARE TEENAGE
YEARS.
THE YOUNGER I THINK LESS
EXPOSURE THE BETTER.
ALL OF US CAN OVERDOSE ON
TELEVISION.
WE SHOULDN'T OVERDO IT IN ANY
WAY.
WE SHOULDN'T OVERDRINK OR
EXERCISE OR ISOLATE.
WE SHOULD TRY TO BE MOD
DEMOCRAT AND IN COMMUNICATION
WITH ONE ANOTHER AND OPEN TO
RECEIVE WHATEVER SUPPORT IS
GOING TO HELP US.
COUNSELORS, RELIGIOUS SUPPORT.
ONE ANOTHER.
>> WELL, OKAY.
AND THEN WHAT HAPPENS WITH THE
CHILDREN AND THE PARENTS WHO
CLEAR LIVE WILL GO INTO A
DEPRESSION?
>> WELL, THAT CAN BE TREATED.
SO I DON'T THINK WE SHOULD
THINK THAT THAT'S A FAILURE.
WE DON'T THINK OF THAT OF ANY
KIND OF A SHORT OR MORAL
UPCOMING.
THAT'S VERY TREATABLE.
WE ARE NOT TALKING ABOUT THE
SHOOTER HERE.
HE PLAY HAVE HAD A CONDITION
TOO.
ANYBODY SUFFERING NOW CAN BE
TREATED AND MOVE TOWARD
HEALING.
>> Judge Jeanine: FINAL
QUESTION BEFORE I GO TO
DR. BARBARA KERWIN A FORENSIC
PSYCHOLOGIST SITTING IN NEW
YORK CITY NOW.
YOU KNOW, WHEN WE SAY CAN THIS
KIND OF THING BE PREVENTED AND
YOU THINK THAT MAYBE IT CAN
BE, IF YOU KNOW ENOUGH ABOUT
THE INDIVIDUAL.
YOU KNOW, MY QUESTION REALLY
IS WHY IS THE WORLD SO
DIFFERENT TODAY?
WHY ARE PEOPLE DOING THIS?
WHY IS THIS BECOMING THE NORM?
>> YOU KNOW, I DON'T HAVE THE
ONE ANSWER FOR THAT.
PEOPLE THINK THAT THERE IS A
TOO MUCH OF CULTURE OF
VIOLENCE.
PEOPLE ARE TOO ISOLATED IN
THEIR OWN MINDS.
THE MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEM ISN'T
AS GOOD AS IT SHOULD BE.
LOVING EMBRACE THAT INSISTED
ON THERAPY OF A MEANINGFUL
SORT THAT HE COULD HAVE
ACCESSED AND AFFORD COULD HAVE
AVOIDED THIS.
>> DOCTOR, THANKS SO MUCH FOR
BEING WITH US THIS EVENING.
KNOW, DOCTOR, YOU RAN THE UNIT
FOR THE VIOLENT CRIMINALLY
INSANE AT CREED MORE.
SO YOU HAVE GOT A LOT OF
EXPERIENCE WITH THIS KIND OF
THING.
WERE THERE A TELL TALE SIGNS
OR ARE THERE PREDICTABLE
ISSUES OR FACTORS THAT WOULD
IDENTIFY THIS INDIVIDUAL AS A
DANGEROUS INDIVIDUAL.
>> WHAT WE'RE SEEING WITH HIM
IS THE STORY THAT WE SEE AGAIN
AND AGAIN WITH THESE COINS OF
CREEPY PEOPLE THAT GO IN AND
UNLEASH THIS TYPE OF VIOLENCE.
HE WAS THE LONER, HE DIDN'T
GET ALONG WITH OTHER PEOPLE.
HE HAD ISSUES IN SCHOOL.
HE WAS BRILL YENT.
BRIGHT AND SOMETHING WAS
DISTURBLILY WRONG AND NOBODY
SEEMED TO TAKE NOTICE OF IT
UNTIL WE HAVE THE UNTHINKABLE.
IT'S NOT SO UNTHINKABLE WHEN
WE HAVE A UNBALANCED PARANOID
ANGRY ISOLATED INDIVIDUAL.
IS HE REALLY FOLLOWING THE
PATTERN OF THAT PARANOID TYPE.
WE HAD JAMES HOLMES OUT IN
AURORA, COLORADO.
A SIMILAR KIND OF PERSONALITY.
AND MY ISSUE IS WHEN ARE WE
GOING TO BECOME AWARE OF THIS?
WHEN ARE WE GOING TO
INTERVENE?
>> Judge Jeanine: DOCTOR, IS
THERE ANY WAY FOR US AS A
SOCIETY TO SAY THIS GUY IS A
LONER, WE BETTER CHECK HIM
OUT?
LOOK, WHEN I WAS A JUDGE, THEY
BRING PEOPLE IN FLONT OF ME
AND SAY HE IS DANGER TO THE
COMMUNITY OR HIMSELF I DO A
PSYCHIATRIC ON HIM.
THIEVES ARE YOWNEL MALES IN
THEIR 20 WE ARE TALKING '.
AURORA, ALL OF THE OTHER
SHOOTINGS AND COLUMBINE AND
ALL OF THAT.
HOW DO WE CATCH THESE PEOPLE.
>> THEY ARE NOT ISOLATED
COMPLETELY A COMMUNITY OF ONE.
NOW THEY ARE KNOW OF PEOPLE
WHO KILLED THIS YOUNG MAN.
HE BASS POOR THE.
I DIDN'T BEHAVE CORRECTLY.
THAT'S WHEN WE NEED TO NOTICE.
THAT'S WHEN WE NEED TO SAY HE
NEEDS TO BE EXAMINED.
HE NEEDS HELP.
MORE STATES THAN NOT HAVE
ASSISTED OUTPATIENT TREATMENT
PROGRAMS.
WE CAN INSIST THAT PEOPLE WHO
SHOW WEIRDNESS, PROCLIVITIES
TRARDZ VIOLENCE, SOCIAL
ISOLATION, BIZARRE THINKING.
>> Judge Jeanine: YOU KNOW
WHAT, DOCTOR, WITH ALL DUE
RESPECT AND YOU ARE CERTAINLY
A WELL RESPECTED DOCTOR AS IS
DR. SHARP.
THIS KID WAS HOME COOD.
THERE HAS GOT TO BE SOMETHING
BECAUSE HIS MOTHER WANTED TO
HOME SCHOOL HIM.
>> WHY DID SHE WANT TO HOME
SCHOOL HIM?
WHAT WAS GOING WRONG?
YOU DON'T PICK A KID OUT OF
SCHOOL AND HOME SCHOOL HIM IF
EVERYTHING IS ROSY FOR HIM IN
SCHOOL UNLESS YOU HAVE A
RELIGIOUS PERSUASION.
>> WHY DID THE MOTHER AND, OF
COURSE, DR. CORWIN AND
DR. SHARP.
WHY DID THE HIS OR HER HAVE
THOSE SEMIAUTOMATICS ON THE
BUSH BLASTER.
BARB SHARP.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US.
THE SHOOTER HAD ACCESS TO AN
ARSENAL EVER WEAPONS.
WHERE DID HE GET THEM AND WHY
DID HE USE THEM?
STAY WITH US.
[ Male Announcer ]
WE ALL MAKE BAD DECISIONS.
LIKE SAY, GAS STATION SUSHI.
CHEAP IS GOOD.
AND SUSHI, GOOD.
BUT CHEAP SUSHI, NOT SO GOOD.
IT'S LIKE THAT SUPER-LOW RATE
ON NOT ENOUGH CAR INSURANCE.
PRETTY SKETCHY.
♪
AND THEN THERE ARE
THE GOOD DECISIONS.
LIKE ESURANCE.
THEIR COVERAGE COUNSELOR TOOL
HELPS YOU CHOOSE
THE RIGHT COVERAGE FOR YOU
AT A GREAT PRICE.
[ stomach growls ]
WITHOUT FEELING QUEASY.
THAT'S INSURANCE
FOR THE MODERN WORLD.
ESURANCE.
NOW BACKED BY ALLSTATE.
CLICK OR CALL.
>> ALL THE WOUNDS THAT I KNOW
OF AT THIS POINT WERE CAUSED
BY THE LONG WEAPON.
THIS TYPE OF WEAPON IS NOT --
THE BULLETS ARE DESIGNED IN
SUCH A FASHION THAT THE
ENERGY, THIS IS VERY CLINICAL.
I SHOULDN'T BE SAYING.
THIS THE ENERGY IS DEPOSITED
IN THE TISSUE SO THE BULLETS
[INAUDIBLE]
>> Judge Jeanine: JOINING ME
NOW WITH MARK FUHRMAN, FOX
NEWS CONTRIBUTOR AND SOMEONE
WHO LIKE ME, HAS BEEN AT MANY
CRIME SCENES INVOLVING YOUNG
CHILDREN.
MARK, ARE YOU THERE?
>> I AM HERE.
>> Judge Jeanine: MARK, I SEE
YOU NOW.
ALL RIGHT, MARK, LOOK, THERE
IS NO QUESTION THAT THE DEVIL
HAD BEEN IN NEWTOWN
CONNECTICUT.
YOU AND I HAVE SEEN OUTCOME
CHILDREN IN HOMICIDE SCENES.
IT IS SOMETHING THAT NOTHING
CAN PREPARE YOU FOR.
BUT THE NUMBER OF CHILDREN IN
THIS SITUATION.
THE NUMBER OF CHILDREN DEAD
AND AS WE HEARD FROM THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER WITH MULTIPLE
WOUNDS HAS TO BE DIFFICULT FOR
THE MOST SEASONED HOMICIDE
DETECTIVE AND THE FIRST
RESPONDERS.
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THAT, MARC?
>> I SAY IT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
IT'S ONE THING THAT YOU DEAL
WITH, SOME OF THE PEOPLE THAT
COMMIT THEIR LIFE TO CRIME.
GANG MEMBERS.
PEOPLE WHO COMMIT TO VIOLENCE.
THEY END UP GETTING SHOT OR
INJURED.
THAT'S ONE THING EVEN A
DOMESTIC SITUATION IS
DIFFERENT INNOCENT CHILDREN.
NOBODY PREPARED FOR.
THIS THE ONLY SCENES THAT I
REALLY REMEMBER THAT I CAN
NEVER ERASE, ONE IS A
4-YEAR-OLD LITTLE GIRL THAT
I'LL NEVER FORGET.
SO, NO, IT NEVER GOES AWAY.
AND THE ONLY WAY YOU DO IS YOU
JUST DETACH YOURSELF AND GET
YOUR JOB DONE AND TRY TO GET
OUT OF THERE.
>> Judge Jeanine: WE BOTH KNOW
IS WHAT YOU DO IS YOU CLOSE
YOUR MIND OFF EMOTIONALLY.
YOU BECOME THE DETECTIVE, I
BECOME THE D.A.
BUT IN THE QUIET OF THE NIGHT,
MARK, YOU AND I BOTH KNOW THAT
SCENE COMES BACK TO US OVER
AND OVER AGAIN.
NOW, MARC, I HAVE SPECIFICALLY
NOT MENTIONED THE NAME OF THE
SHOOTER.
I WOULDN'T GIVE HIM THAT.
I WOULDN'T GIVE HIM ANYTHING
OTHER THAN WHAT HE DESERVES IF
HE WERE TO LIVE.
BUT, WHAT DO WE DO ABOUT THE
FACT THAT WE HAVE GOT SCHOOLS
WHERE OUR CHILDREN ARE THAT
WE'RE NOT ABLE TO PROTECT
THEM?
I MEAN, WHAT DO MOST SCHOOLS
HAVE?
SHOULD THERE BE ARMED GUARDS
AT OUR SCHOOLS IN THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS?
WHAT DO YOU THINK SHOULD
HAPPEN?
>> WELL, WE ADDRESS TERRORISM
BY TRYING TO FORTIFY OR MAKE
SOFT TARGETS HARD TARGETS.
THAT'S REALLY WHAT WE NEED TO
DO.
EVERYTHING ELSE CAN COME AFTER
THAT.
BUT YOU NEED TO MAKE IT AS
DIFFICULT AS POSSIBLE FOR
SOMEBODY THAT'S NOT AUTHORIZED
TO GET INTO ANY SCHOOL.
THAT IS THE FIRST STEP.
UNTIL THAT STEP IS MET, THEN
YOU CAN'T GO FORWARD WITH A
PLAINED CLOTHES POLICE OFFICER
OR SECURITY OR ANYTHING ELSE
EVEN TRAINING SOME OF THE
TEACHER WHAT IS TO DO.
YOU HAVE TO FIRST MAKE A
BARRICADE.
AND MAKE IT A HARDER TARGET
BECAUSE RIGHT NOW EVERY
SUSPECT THAT WANTS TO COMMIT
THIS TYPE OF VIOLENCE KNOWS
THAT THEY WILL GET ON THE
PROPERTY AND THEY WILL GET
INSIDE.
>> WELL, AND THAT'S THE HARD
PART.
BUT YOU KNOW MAYBE WE NEED TO
LEARN FROM THE SCHOOLS IN
ISRAEL.
SCHOOLS IN IRELAND WHO HAVE
ALL TAKEN PRECAUTIONS FOR
THEIR CHILDREN AND, YOU KNOW,
WE LIVE IN A FREE SOCIETY.
I DON'T KNOW IF THERE IS ANY
WAY TO PROTECT AGAINST.
THIS MARK FUHRMAN THANKS SO
MUCH FOR BEING WITH US THIS
EVENING.
>> THANK YOU, JUDGE.
>> Judge Jeanine: COMING UP,
WE HAVE ALL HAD OUR FAITH
SHANE BY THE EVIL THAT
CONFRONTED US YESTERDAY IN THE
FORM OF A 20-YEAR-OLD IN BLACK
FATIGUES AND A MILITARY STYLE
VET.
AFTER THE BREAK, WHAT CAN WE
DO TO COME TO GRIPS WITH THIS
HORRIFIC TRAGEDY?
[ Sarah ] I THOUGHT,
THE RED CROSS DOES KATRINA.
THEY DON'T HELP SINGLE MOMS.
HI!
[ Sarah ] WHAT HAPPENED
TO OUR HOUSE LAST YEAR?
[ Daughters ] IT FLOODED
AND THE WATER FLOODED OUT. YEAH.
[ Sarah ] THE RED CROSS
ARRANGED THE HOTEL FOR US.
THEY GAVE ME THAT BREAK,
THAT LEVERAGE,
TO BE ABLE TO GET IT TOGETHER
AND TAKE CARE OF THEM. YOU KNOW?
I FEEL LIKE WE'VE COME
FULL CIRCLE.
[ Daughter 1 ] LIKE THAT!
[ Daughter 2 ]
THIS IS HOW I'LL DO IT.
[ Sarah ] THERE YOU GO.
>> THE PAIN IN THIS TOWN IS
PALPABLE.
THE DEVIL WAS HERE YESTERDAY.
HOW DOES ONE EVEN BEGIN TO
HEAL AFTER THE PHYSICAL AND
THE EMOTIONAL TRAUMA THAT SO
MANY EXPERIENCED.
DONNA MORSI IS A SPOKESPERSON
WITH THE RED CROSS.
ALSO WITH ME IS SPARTICUS AND
HIS HANDLER BRAD.
DONNA, I UNDERSTAND THAT YOU
CAME IN FROM BOSTON AS SOON AS
YOU HEARD ABOUT THIS.
LET ME SAY ONE THING ABOUT THE
RED CROSS, WE LOST OUR HOME IN
UPSTATE NEW YORK.
THE RED CROSS WAS THERE AND
BROUGHT FOOD TO US.
WE HADN'T EATEN IN A WHILE AND
I WANT THANK YOU ON BEHALF OF
SO MANY PEOPLE.
BUT WHAT DID YOU SEE, HEAR
COMPARED TO SOME OF THIS
STUFF, WHO HORRIFIC STUFF I'M SE
THAT YOU HAVE ALREADY SEEN?
>> CLEAR THERE SUN IMAGINABLE
TRAGEDY CONDOLENCES GO OUT
HOUSES OF WORSHIP.
PEOPLE WITH GRIEF ACROSS THEIR
FACES.
WE HAVE OVER 100 RED CROSS
WORKERS ON THE GROUND.
PROVIDING FOOD AND WATER.
MOST IMPORTANTLY EMOTIONAL
SUPPORT.
MENTAL HEALTH COUNSELING, NOT
ONLY TO THE FAMILIES AFFECTED
AND THE LARGER COMMUNITY BUT
TO THE FIRST RESPONDER WHO'S
HAVE BEEN SO PROFOUNDLY
AFFECTED?
>> Judge Jeanine: PEOPLE WHO
HAVEN'T SEEN THIS KIND OF
THING BEFORE.
I'M GOING TO GO TO YOU, BRAD,
NOW, YOU WERE HERE, HEY, GOOD
LUCK AND NOW YOU DECIDE, OH,
SITTING HERE QUIETLY WAITING
FOR HIS SHOT AND OF COURSE HE
JUST JUMPED DOWN.
SPARIKUS.
TELL US ABOUT HIM.
>> IS HE A 3-YEAR-OLD AKITA.
IS HE A CERTIFIED THERAPY DOG.
>> WHAT IS A THERAPY DOG.
WHAT DOES A THERAPY DOG DO.
>> PROVIDES COMFORT AND LOVE
TO THOSE WHO NEED HIM.
WE VOLUNTEER IN HOSPITAL
LOCALLY, SO WE VISIT WITH
CHILDREN AND PATIENTS HE SITS
THERE AND HANGS OUT WITH HIM.
PEOPLE WILL SIT THERE AND FEEL
COMFORTABLE.
DECOMPRESS WHAT'S GOING ON WHY
WORK TODAY AND LAST NIGHT WITH
CHILDREN AND THEIR FAMILIES.
WHEN COUNSELORS INVITE US IN.
BE WITH THE CHILD AND/OR
CHILDREN.
AND THE.
>> THEY ARE NOT AFRAID OF HIM
IN HE IS BIG AND BY THE WAY IS
HE BEAUTIFUL.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU CAN SEE
HIS EYES, HE WAS SITTING
QUIETLY FOR A FEW MINUTES.
IS HE A MAGNIFICENT DOG.
YOU ARE NOT WORRIED ABOUT A
CHILD UPSETTING HIM?
HE WON'T GET UPSET AND WON'T
BITE?
>> NO.
IS HE A VERY -- THERAPY DOGS
ONE OF THEIR QUALITIES ARE
THEY NEED TO LOVE CHILDREN.
BE GOOD AROUND ALL SORTS OF
ACTIVITY.
HE LOST CHILDREN BECAUSE OF
THE VOLUNTEER WORK DOING AT A
LOCAL HOSPITAL APPROPRIATE TO
COME UP AND BE WITH THE
CHILDREN TO HELP DECOMPRESS
FIRST RESPONDERS AND TEACHERS
AS WELL.
>> IS THIS NEW HAVING A DOG
COME IN.
I DON'T REMEMBER SEEING THIS
KIND OF THING USING A DOG AS
THERAPY.
>> NO MUCH.
IT'S WELL DOCUMENTED.
NOT WELL KNOWN MANY TIMES.
IN SPATICUS CASE FIRST TIME I
CONSIDERED MAKING HIM THERAPY
DOG 8 MONTHS OLD AND AUTISTIC
CHILD CAME UP TO US IN NEW
HAVEN GREEN.
8 YEARS OLD.
HE STAYED WITH US TWO AND A
HALF HOURS.
HE WAS VERY ARTICULATE.
WHEN HE LEFT US HE ASIDE FROM
THIS, THAT MAY BE ABLE TO GET
THEM PAST THE HUMP.
GETTING A DOG TO FOCUS ON FOR
THE CHILDREN WHO EITHER SAW
SOMETHING THAT HAPPENED IN
SCHOOL OR THE SIBLINGS OF
CHILDREN WHO HAVE BEEN LOST.
>> RED CROSS HAS STRESSED THE
IMPORTANCE OF PARENTS TALKING
TO THEIR KIDS, TALKING TO THEM
ABOUT THEIR FEARS TALKING
ABOUT THEIR SAFETY.
EVEN THE MOST SEASONED OF
VOLUNTEERS.
WE ARE HUMAN FIRST.
SO WE'RE HERE TAKING CARE OF
EACH OTHER COMING TOGETHER AS
A COMMUNITY.
MENTAL HEALTH COUNSELORS AND
PEOPLE CAN HELP YOU DEAL WITH
YOUR GRIEFS.
SO IMPORTANT.
>> Judge Jeanine: I WANT TO
THANK YOU DONNA MORSI AGAIN
ALL THAT YOU DO WITH THE RED
CROSS.
THANKS SO MUCH FOR BEING WITH
US.
OF COURSE, SPARTICUS -- HE IS
STARTING TO TURN AROUND.
ANYWAY, GOOD NIGHT, EVERYONE.
THANKS FOR BEING WITH US.
HOPEFULLY YOU JOIN US TOMORROW
NIGHT FOR ANOTHER SPECIAL
EDITION OF 9:00 OF JUSTICE.
THE INTERCOM IN THE OFFICE
WENT OFF AS IF THEY WERE GOING
IT MAKE ANNOUNCEMENT.
SCUFFLING NOISES.
I THOUGHT SOMEBODY HIT THE
BUTTON BY MISTAKE AND THEY
WERE IN THE OFFICE.
ONE OF THE SECRETARIES
ANSWERED THE PHONE AND SAID
THERE WAS A SHOOTING.
>> MAYHEM IN THE ROOM WITH ALL
THE KIDS AND TEACHERS TRYING
TO FIND YOUR KID.
IDENTIFY WHERE YOURS IS AND
MAKING SURE THEY ARE SAFE.
FIND OUT WHAT THE SITUATION
WAS.
>> SHE WAS IN A SMALL CLASS.
A READING GROUP AND THEY
STARTED HEARING, I GUESS,
BANGS.
AND HER TEACHER WHICH I'M SO
GRATEFUL FOR, THERE WAS JUST A
SMALL GROUP, THEY RUSHED THE
KIDS INTO THE BATHROOM, AND
THEY LOCKED THE DOOR.
AND THEY JUST TOLD THE
CHILDREN THAT IT WAS HAMMERING
AND TRIED TO KEEP THEM CALM.
THE NEXT THING I KNOW BECAUSE
IT'S VERY HARD TO GET THE
COMPLETE STORY.
THE NEXT THING I KNOW IS THAT
THE POLICE CAME IN AND THEY
WERE KNOCKING ON THE DOOR TO
BE LET OUT.
OF THE CLASSROOM.
AND WHEN THEY WERE, SHE HAD
SEEN GLASS AND BLOOD.
ONE CHILD WAS COVERED IN BLOOD
BUT I UNDERSTAND THAT CHILD IS
SAFE AND WAS NOT HURT AND MUST
HAVE BEEN SOMEBODY ELSE'S.
>> IT'S SHEAR TERROR AND A
SENSE OF IMMEDIATE URGENCY.
AND, YOU KNOW, TO GET TO YOUR
CHILD AND TO BE THERE TO
PROTECT THEM.
>> 18 CHILDREN PRONOUNCED DEAD
AT THE SCHOOL.
THERE WERE TWO THAT WERE
TRANSPORTED TO AREA HOSPITALS
AND PRONOUNCED DEAD AT AREA
HOSPITALS.
THERE WERE SIX ADULTS
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCENE
AT THE SCHOOL.
>> WE HAVE ENDURED TOO MANY OF
THESE TRAGEDIESED IN THE PAST
FEW YEARS.
AND EACH TIME I LEARN THE
NEWS, I REACT NOT AS A
PRESIDENT BUT AS ANYBODY ELSE
WOULD, AS A PARENT.
THAT WAS ESPECIALLY TRUE
TODAY.
I KNOW THERE IS NOT A PARENT
IN AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL
THE SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF
THAT I DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS
OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN