VICTIMS.
>> Kelly: AND RICK AND JAMIE
ARE GOING TO JOIN YOU FROM
HERE AND KEEP PRAYING FOR THE
PEOPLE IN
>>  WELL, DISTURBING NEW
DEVELOPMENTS ARE UNRAVELLING
BY THE MINUTE IN THE TRAGIC
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTING.
RIGHT NOW THE DEATH TOLL
STANDS AT 28.
27 OF THEM THE VICTIMS.
SO MANY OF THEM CHILDREN.
THE OTHER, THE GUNMAN, HELLO
EVERYONE, I'M JAMIE COLBY, A
BRAND NEW HOUR INSIDE
AMERICA'S NEWS ROOM.
>> Rick: I'M RICK FOLBAUM AND
POLICE ARE SAYING THEY HAVE
GOOD EVIDENCE TO BEGIN TO
EXPLAIN WHY 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM
LANZA OPENED FIRE ON INNOCENT
CHILDREN AND ON THOSE
EDUCATORS AS WELL.
THE GUNMAN IS SEEN HERE IN A
PICTURE TAKEN A NUMBER OF
YEARS AGO AND WE'RE NOW
LEARNING THAT DESPITE EARLIER
REPORTS THAT THIS YOUNG MAN'S
MOTHER WORKED AT THE SCHOOL,
POLICE ARE NOW SAYING THAT
THAT HE HAVE BEEN UNABLE TO
ESTABLISH ANY CONNECTION
BETWEEN THE MOTHER AND THE
SCHOOL.
>> Jamie: SO MANY THINGS
DEVELOPING THIS HOUR.
WE'LL HAVE A LOT OF NEW
INFORMATION.
AT THIS HOUR POLICE SAY
THEY'VE NOW IDENTIFIED ALL OF
THE VICTIMS IN THE TRAGEDY AS
THEY WORKED TIRELESSLY TO COMB
THE CRIME SCENE.
>> WE STILL HAVE MAJOR CRIME
DETECTIVES AND NEWTOWN
DETECTIVES WORKING AT THE
SCENE IN THE SCHOOL.
THAT'S NOT COMPLETED AND THAT
PROBABLY WILL NOT BE COMPLETED
FOR AT LEAST ANOTHER DAY AND A
HALF TO TWO DAYS AND I'M
PUTTING A TIME LIMIT ON IT, IT
COULD TAKE LONGER.
AS I'VE EXPLAINED IN PREVIOUS
PRESS CONFERENCES, WE'VE DONE
EVERYTHING WE NEED TO DO TO
LITERALLY PEEL BACK THE ONION
LAYER BY LAYER AND EXAMINE
EVERY CRACK AND CREVICE OF
THAT FACILITY AND THAT DOES
NOT INCLUDE--
OR EXCLUDE, I SHOULD SAY THE
OUTSIDE OF THE BUILDING.
THE OUTSIDE OF THE BUILDING IS
ALSO PART OF THE CRIME SCENE
EVERY SINGLE VEHICLE IN THAT
LOT.
IT'S GOING TO BE PAINSTAKING
PROCESS.
OUR INVESTIGATOR AT THE CRIME
SCENE AND AT THE SCHOOL AND
SECONDARILY AT THE SECONDARY
CRIME SCENE WE USED WHERE A
FEMALE WAS DECEASED, COULD
PROVIDE GOOD EVIDENCE IN THIS
INVESTIGATION, THAT OUR
INVESTIGATORS WILL BE ABLE TO
USE AND HOPEFULLY PAINTING A
COMPLETE PICTURE HOW, AND MORE
IMPORTANTLY, WHY THIS
OCCURRED.
WE HAVE ESTABLISHED A POINT OF
ENTRY.
IT WAS, I CAN TELL YOU IT
WAS--
I UNDERSTAND BELIEVED HE WAS
NOT VOLUNTARILY LET INTO THE
SCHOOL AT ALL, THAT HE FORCED
HIS WAY INTO THE SCHOOL, AS
FAR AS WE CAN GO ON THAT.
NOW TO THE SHOOTING.
WE DID A THOROUGH SEARCH OF
THE NEIGHBORHOOD AND LOCAL
PARTNERS AND EVERYTHING WAS
EXAMINED.
IF WE FOUND ANYONE IN THE
WOODS CUTTING WOOD, THEY WOULD
BE DETAINED PENDING
INVESTIGATION.
SO, THERE WERE NO OTHER
ARRESTS THAT WERE ASSOCIATED
WITH THIS INVESTIGATION.
>> AWE NOW OUR CORRESPONDENT
MOLLY LINE IS LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
I KNOW IT'S A HARD STORY TO
COVER.
AT THIS HOUR DO YOU HAVE NEW
INFORMATION ABOUT THE GUNMAN'S
MOTHER?
>> YES, ACTUALLY, MORE THAN 24
HOURS HAVE PASSED NOW SINCE
THIS MASSACRE OCCURRED AND
FEDERAL AUTHORITIES ARE NOW
SAYING THAT THE GUNMAN'S
MOTHER, NANCY LANZA, WHO WAS
NOT AFFILIATED WITH THE
SCHOOL.
SO, INFORMATION HAS CHANGED
AND INITIALLY REPORTED THAT
SHE HAD SOME SORT OF
AFFILIATION, POSSIBLY A
TEACHER, POSSIBLY A
KINDERGARTEN TEACHER AND THAT
RAISES MORE QUESTIONS BECAUSE
INITIALLY PEOPLE THOUGHT IF
SHE HAD A CONNECTION TO THE
SCHOOL, IT MIGHT EXPLAIN SOME
OF THE GUNMAN'S ANGER AND WHY
HE WENT TO THAT LOCATION.
TO SEEK SOMEHOW A MOTIVE AND
NOW, FEDERAL AUTHORITIES ARE
SAYING THAT'S NOT THE CASE AND
THERE IS NO CONNECTION AND
THAT REALLY RAISES A LOT MORE
QUESTIONS ABOUT HOW THINGS
HAPPENED AND WHY THEY
HAPPENED.
OTHER INFORMATION HAS CHANGED
OFF THE COURSE OF THIS
INVESTIGATION.
MOST NOTABLY, THE NAME OF THE
SHOOTER WAS INITIALLY REPORTED
TO BE RYAN LANZA, THE BROTHER
OF THE SHOOTING AND HE WAS
TAKE BE INTO CUSTODY AND
SPEAKING AND COOPERATING WITH
AUTHORITIES AND RELEASED.
IT IS BELIEVED THAT ADAM
LANZA, THE SHOOTER, HAD TAKEN
RYAN LANZA'S IDENTIFICATION IN
THE SCHOOL WITH HIM.
AND EVERY TIME THERE'S A PRESS
CONFERENCE, WE GET A LITTLE
MORE INFORMATION AND A LITTLE
MORE THE PUZZLE ALTHOUGH WE
MAY NEVER KNOW EXACTLY WHY
THIS SENSELESS EPISODE
HAPPENED.
JAMIE.
>> Jamie: ALTHOUGH AT THE
POLICE CONFERENCE, THEY DID
SAY THEY HAVE EFFECTIVE
EVIDENCE THAT THEY FOUND THAT
MIGHT EXPLAIN MOTIVE.
IF YOU CAN EVER EXPLAIN SUCH A
THING.
THEY'VE DONE A LOT OF
INTERVIEWS IN THE LAST 24
HOURS, MOLLY.
AND THERE WAS ONE SURVIVOR
THAT COULD PROVE KEY TO THIS.
WHAT HAVE YOU LEARNED ACTUALLY
HAPPENED DURING THIS TRAGEDY?
>> YEAH, THE SURVIVE YOU'RE
TALKING ABOUT WAS A SHOOTING
VICTIM THAT GOT OUT AND MADE
IT TO THE HOSPITAL AND IS
EXPECTED TO RECOVER AND THEY
SAY THAT WHAT SHE HAS TO SAY
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED INSIDE
THAT BUILDING WILL BE
INVALUABLE TO THEM AS THEY TRY
TO UNROUGHLY THE FACTS AND OF
COURSE, THEY HAVE SO MANY,
DOZENS AND DOZENS OF FIRSTHAND
ACCOUNTS OF PEOPLE INSIDE THE
SCHOOL WHEN THE SHOOTING
OCCURRED, THAT HEARD THE
GUNSHOTS AND WE HAD A CHANCE
TO SPEAK WITH A LIBRARIAN THAT
SURVIVED AND HERE IS WHAT SHE
HAD TO SAY ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
INSIDE.
>> THE INTERCOM IN THE THE
OFFICE WENT OFF AS IF THEY
WERE GOING TO MAKE AN
ANNOUNCEMENT AND THEN WE HEARD
SOME SCUFFLING NOISES AND
STUFF AND I THOUGHT THAT
SOMEBODY HIT THE BUTTON BY
MISTAKE AND THEY WERE JUST IN
THE OFFICE AND SO I CALLED
DOWN THERE AND ONE OF THE
SECRETARIES ANSWERED THE PHONE
AND SAID THERE'S A SHOOTING
AND THEN YOU BECOME AWARE AND
WE STARTED HEARING THE
GUNSHOTS, SO, I YELLED
LOCKDOWN, TO THE GROUP THAT
WAS IN OUR ROOM AND I RAN
ACROSS THE HALL AND TOLD THEM
TO LOCK DOWN.
>> AND THE NUMBER OF PEOPLE
THAT ARE AFFECTED AND ARE PART
OF THIS INVESTIGATION FROM THE
CHILDREN TO THE SCHOOL
PERSONNEL, THE TEACHERS, THE
PARENTS, THE MULTIPLE LAW
ENFORCEMENT AGENCIES ON THE
GROUND HERE, THE GOVERNMENT
AGENCIES, SCHOOL PERSONNEL,
THERE ARE SO MANY DIFFERENT
FACTS TO UNCOVER AND MANY,
MANY DAYS AHEAD.
DETECTIVES SAY THEY'LL BE AT
THE SCHOOL FOR DAYS AND THAT'S
JUST THE BEGINNING AS THIS
COMMUNITY COPES WITH WHAT
OCCURRED HERE, JAMIE.
>> Jamie: IF THEY CAN, SO
TRAGIC.
MOLLY STAY ON IT FOR US, BRING
US ANY NEW DETAILS OVER THE
HOUR THAT RICK AND I ARE HERE.
>> Rick: OUT OF THE TRAGEDY,
SO MANY HEROIC STAFF MEMBERS
WHO SACRIFICED THEIR OWN LIVES
IN THE ATTEMPT TO SAVE THE
YOUNG KIDS.
THIS IS A PICTURE OF THE
PRINCIPAL OF THE SCHOOL.
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, AND OTHERS
HID UNDER TABLES ONCE THE
GUNFIRE BEGAN, THE PRINCIPAL
RAN STRAIGHT FOR THE GUNMAN
THAN THAT MOVE ENDED UP
COSTING HER HER LIFE.
AND THE HER FRIEND, THE
LIBRARIAN WE HEARD ABOUT IN
MOLLY'S REPORT ALSO TOOK TIME
TO SPEAK ABOUT PRINCIPAL
HOCHSPRUNG.
>> WE HAD A BOOK FAIR A FEW
WEEKS AGO AND SHE DRESSED UP
AS A READING FAIRY AND PUTTING
READING FAIRIE DUST ON THE
KIDS.
SHE WAS JUST AN AMAZING WOMAN,
SHE WAS STRONG AND FUN AND THE
KIDS LOVED HER AND, SHE WAS A
REALLY WONDERFUL WOMAN, IT'S A
HUGE LOSS FOR THE TOWN AND FOR
OUR SCHOOL.
WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT HOW OUR
SCHOOL IS GOING TO RECOVER,
YOU THINK ABOUT LEADERSHIP AND
SHE'S THE PERSON WHO MOST
COULD HAVE DONE THAT.
>> ALONG WITH THE PRINCIPAL,
TWO OTHER STAFF MEMBERS DIED
TRYING TO SAVE THEIR STUDENTS.
27-YEAR-OLD LAURIE SOTO, THREW
HER BODY IN FRONT OF THE
CHILDREN AS THE GUNMAN STARTED
SHOOTING.
AND THE 56-YEAR-OLD
PSYCHOLOGIST WHO RAN INTO THE
HALLWAY ALONG WITH THE
PRINCIPAL AND CONFRONTED THE
SHOOTER AND THEY WERE BOTH
GUNNED DOWN MOMENTS LATER.
>> WORD OF THE SHOOTING
SENDING STOCK WAVES THROUGH
THE SMALL, CLOSE KNIT
COMMUNITY WE'RE GETTING TO
KNOW.
PARENTS AND LOVED ONES,
RUSHING TO THE SCHOOL NOT
KNOWING IF THEIR CHILDREN WERE
STILL ALIVE.
AND HERE IS MORE FROM FRIENDS
AND NEIGHBORS.
>> THEY JUST TOLD US -- JUST
TOLD US IF YOU CAN'T FIND YOUR
KIDS, IF YOU CAN'T FIND YOUR
CHILDREN THEY'RE DEAD IN THE
BUILDING.
OH.
>> AND MY, MY BEST FRIEND'S
CHILD IS MISSING AND THE
STUDENTS THEY TOOK TO THE
HOSPITAL ARE DEAD NOW.
AND YOU CAN PRETTY MUCH ASSUME
THAT THE ONES IN THE, IN THE
HOSPITAL -- I MEAN, IN THE,
THAT ARE IN THE SCHOOL ARE
DEAD.
EVERYBODY IN THE SCHOOL IS
>> THERE'S NO WORD AND I THINK
EVERYONE IS IN SHOCK.
AND MY DAUGHTER AND A COUPLE
OF OTHER FRIENDS, FROM
COLLEGE, THEY WERE HERE LAST
NIGHT AND ALL PRETTY MUCH IN
SHOCK AND NO ONE CAN BELIEVE
WHAT'S GOING ON.
>> THIS TOWN IS 300 YEARS OLD
AND THIS IS PROBABLY THE WORST
DAY IN THE HISTORY OF THIS
TO
TOWN.
AND IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE THAT
ANYTHING LIKE THIS COULD
HAPPEN.
IT'S A VERY QUIET DOWN, MAYBE
IT'S TOO QUIET.
IT'S HORRIBLE THAT SUCH EVIL
EXISTS IN THE UNITED STATES
AND IN SANDY HOOK IN
PARTICUL
PARTICULAR, BUT THAT'S THE
NATURE OF THE WORLD WE LIVE
IN, I GUESS.
>> EVIL WITHOUT A DOUBT.
SO CLOSE TO CHRISTMAS IN THE
MIDDLE OF HANUKKAH, WE'RE
HEARING SOME FOLKS IN NEWTOWN
ARE EVEN TAKING DOWN THEIR
DECORATIONS AND TELLING
REPORTERS THEY FEEL GUILTY
WHILE CELEBRATING ANYTHING,
>> INVESTIGATORS ARE POURING
OVER THE SCHOOL INCH BY INCH
AS WE HEARD JUST A FEW MOMENTS
AGO, A CLEARER PICTURE IS
STARTING TO EMERGE AS WELL OF
THE SHOOTER, AND ADAM LANZA,
SPEAKING IT VARIOUS MEDIA
OUTLETS, DESCRIBING A TERRIBLE
YOUNG MAN AND SOME SAYING IT'S
A HIDDEN TIME BOMB AND JOINING
US NOW IS FORMER NEW YORK CITY
DETECTIVE JOHN BASSA.
AND FIRST OF ALL, I WANT TO
TALK TO YOU ABOUT THE YOUNG
MAN, BUT THE CRIME SCENE
ITSELF AND WE HEARD FROM THE
POLICE LIEUTENANT AT THE TOP
OF THE HOUR TALKING ABOUT THE
CRIME SCENE STILL BEING VERY
ACTIVE.
WE KNOW THAT THE VICTIMS ARE
STILL INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
AS FAR AS WE KNOW.
FIRST OF ALL, WHY MUST THEY BE
LEFT IN THERE FOR SO LONG AND
NOT RETURNED TO THEIR LOVED
ONES AND WHAT'S GOING ON NOW
AS FAR AS THE COLLECTION OF
EVIDENCE?
>> WELL, RIGHT NOW, THEY HAVE
TO -- YOU KNOW, THEY'RE GOING
TO HAVE TO IDENTIFY SOME OF
THE VICTIMS.
THEY'RE STILL GOING TO HAVE TO
BE TAKING PHOTOGRAPHS, NOW, BE
COLLECTING EVIDENCE, BUT WITH
-- AS FAR AS THE BODIES OF THE
CHILDREN, THEY'RE GOING TO
NEED TO IDENTIFY THEM FIRST
BEFORE THEY TAKE THEM OUT TO
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER'S OFFICE.
>> Rick: WE'VE ACTUALLY HEARD
WITHIN THE LAST HOUR OR SO,
THAT ALL THE VICTIMS HAVE IN
FACT BEEN IDENTIFIED AND
THAT'S NEW INFORMATION THAT'S
COME OVER RECENTLY, DETECTIVE.
BUT AS WE TAKE A LOOK AT THE
WORK THAT STILL LIES AHEAD FOR
THE INVESTIGATORS, WHAT DO
THEY HAVE TO DO?
>> WELL, I THINK WHAT THEY'RE
GOING TO TRY TO DO, THEY'RE
GOING TO TRY TO LOOK FOR A
MOTIVE.
I MEAN, THAT'S WHAT WE LOOK
FOR AND THERE'S ALWAYS A
MOTIVE.
ALWAYS A MOTIVE, BUT IF THEY
FIND ONE, IT MAY--
IF THEY FIND ONE, IT MAY BE
VERY, VERY DIFFICULT FOR
ANYONE TO EVEN GRASP OR
UNDERSTAND, WHAT NEEDS TO
HAPPEN NOW AND WHAT I REALLY
OPPOSE THE NOTION OF IS THAT
PEOPLE WANT TO MOURN AND I
AGREE WITH THAT.
I HAVE FIVE CHILDREN MYSELF,
BUT I ALSO WANT TO BE ABLE TO
TAKE ACTION SO THAT THIS WON'T
HAPPEN.
THREE OF MY CHILDREN ARE GOING
TO BE GOING TO ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL ON MONDAY SO WE NEED TO
TAKE SOME ACTION AND AS A
POLICE OFFICER, I CAN TELL YOU
WHAT NEEDS TO BE DONE IS THESE
GUN-FREE SCHOOL ZONES, THAT
NEEDS TO BE REPEALED.
WE HAVE TO HAVE PROTECTION
THERE AND WE HAVE TO HAVE THE
ABILITY FOR TEACHERS AND YOU
KNOW, PEOPLE ON THE CAMPUSES
TO BE ABLE TO DEFEND
THEMSELVES AND TO PROTECT
THESE YOUNG CHILDREN.
>> Rick: SO WHAT YOU'RE
TALKING ABOUT HAVING SOMEONE
ARMED AND TRAINED INSIDE EVERY
SCHOOL AROUND THE COUNTRY IN
THE EVENT OF SOMETHING LIKE
THIS HAPPENING.
>> I'M NOT TALKING ABOUT
NECESSARILY HIRING OR HAVING A
POLICE STATE, BUT TALKING
ABOUT ALLOWING TEACHERS AND,
YOU KNOW, OTHER PERSONNEL THAT
WORK AT THE SCHOOL TO HAVE THE
ABILITY TO HAVE A WEAPON.
IF THAT PRINCIPAL, AND I KNOW
IT'S A VERY TRAGIC INCIDENT,
BUT IF THAT PRINCIPAL HAD A
WEAPON.
THERE HAVE BEEN A CHANCE TO
SAVE HER OWN LIFE, BUT WE NEED
TO TAKE THIS NOTION OF, YOU
KNOW, NOT TAKING ACTION NOW,
WE REALLY NEED TO TAKE ACTION
NOW AND WE NEED TO LOOK AT
THIS AND TAKE ACTION AND DO IT
BECAUSE IF YOU LOOK AT THE
MASS MURDERS THAT WE'VE HAD,
AND MOST OF THEM, AND THE OF
ONES THAT ARE ON TV ALL THE
TIME.
THEY HAPPEN IN GUN-FREE ZONES
AND THIS IS SOMETHING THAT WE
HAVE TO LEARN AND WE HAVE TO
PROTECT OUR CHILDREN AND I
WANT TO PROTECT MY THREE
CHILDREN GOING TO ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, SO, THAT'S VERY
IMPORTANT, TOO, SHOULD BE
IMPORTANT TO EVERYBODY.
>> DETECTIVE.
WHAT WOULD YOU HAVE TEACHERS
AND EDUCATORS ARM THEMSELVES
WITH AND HAVE THE AMMUNITION
THAT THIS YOUNG MAN HAD THAT
ALLOWED HIM TO KILL SO MANY
PEOPLE IN THREE MINUTES?
>> SURE, THEY SHOULD.
THEY SHOULD HAVE ANY
AMMUNITION THEY COULD WANT.
THE THING HERE IS, THE BOTTOM
LINE, WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT
AMMUNITION OR WEAPONS, THE
BOTTOM LINE IS, THEY NEED
SOMETHING AND IT COULD BE
ANYTHING, ANY TYPE OF FIREARM,
TO SAVE THE CHILDREN.
IF YOU WERE TO GIVE ME A MAJOR
WAND AND I COULD CHANGE THINGS
I WOULD HAVE THAT PRINCIPAL OR
SOME OF THE TEACHERS ARMED.
IT COULD HAVE SAVED MORE OF
THE STUDENTS AND STAFF THAT
WERE KILLED.
AND IT'S VERY IMPORTANT.
>> Rick: JOHN IS A FORMER NEW
YORK CITY POLICE DETECTIVES
WITH A DIFFERENT TAKE ON THIS.
DIFFERENT FROM WHAT A LOT OF
PEOPLE AROUND THE COUNTRY ARE
THINKING AND MIGHT LISTEN TO
YOUR REMEDY AND SCRATCH THEIR
HEADS A LITTLE BIT, BUT YOU
CERTAINLY COME AT THIS FROM A
CAREER IN LAW ENFORCEMENT AND
WE APPRECIATE YOU COMING ON
AND SHARING YOUR THOUGHTS WITH
US.
>> THANK YOU, RICK.
>> Jamie: PRESIDENT OBAMA
DEVOTING HIS WEEKLY INTERNET
AND RADIO ADDRESS.
AND TAKE A LOOK AT THE WHITE
HOUSE YOU CAN SEE THE FLAG IS
LOWERED HALF STAFF FOLLOWING
T
THE VICTIMS.
MOLLY, WHAT DO YOU EXPECT TO
COME OUT THIS HAVE AS A RESULT
OF THE TRAGEDY?
>> I EXPECT THE PRESIDENT TO
BE CONSOLER IN CHIEF.
THAT'S WHAT HE SAYS.
HE SAID, QUOTE, OUR HEARTS ARE
BROKEN TODAY.
THAT'S WHAT THE PRESIDENT SAID
IN HIS SATURDAY RADIO AND
INTERNET ADDRESS AND HE DEVO
DEVOTED THE ENTIRE ADDRESS AND
NATION GRIEVES FOR LOSS OF
LOVED ONES.
>> THIS WEEKEND MICHELLE AND I
ARE DOING WHAT PARENTS RP
DOING, HOLDING OUR CHILDREN AS
CLOSE AS WE CAN AND REMINDING
THEM HOW MUCH WE LOVE THEM.
AND THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO ARE NOT DOING
THAT TODAY.
WHILE NOTHING COULD REPLACE
THE LOST AFTER LOVED ONE, WE
CAN EXTEND A HAND IN NEED TO
REMIND THEM THAT WE'RE THERE
FOR THEM.
>> Reporter:  AGAIN, A
PICTURES OF THE WHITE HOUSE,
FLAGS WERE LOWERED TO HALF
STAFF AT BOTH THE WHITE HOUSE
AND CAPITOL IN HONOR OF THOSE
WHO WERE KILLED.
REPUBLICANS IN CONGRESS
USUALLY DO A SATURDAY ADDRESS
OF THEIR OWN, BUT NOT TODAY.
G.O.P. HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER SAID THERE WOULD BE NO
REPUBLICAN ADDRESS TODAY SHOW
THAT PRESIDENT OBAMA COULD
SPEAK FOR THE ENTIRE NATION AT
THIS TIME OF MOURNING AND
SPEAKER BOEHNER DID SAY ON A
PAPER STATEMENT, THE HORROR OF
THIS DOOR SEEMS UNBEARABLE,
BUT WE WILL LOCK ARM BECAUSE
THAT'S HOW AMERICANS RISE
AGAINST UNSPEAKABLE EVENT.
LET US COME TOGETHER IN GOD'S
GRACE FOR THE FAMILIES OF THE
VICTIMS THAT THEY MAY FIND
SOME COMFORT AND PEACE AMID
SUCH SUFFERING.
THERE ARE SOME CALLING FOR
TOUGHER GUN LAWS IN THE WEEK
OF THE SHOOTING.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID THAT THE
COUNTRY DOES NEED TO QUOTE,
TAKE MEANINGFUL ACTIONS TO
PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE
THIS.
BACK TO YOU.
>> Rick: OUTSIDE THE
HEADQUARTERS AT FOX NEWS, WE
ALSO HAVE OUR FLAGS AT HALF
STAFF.
>> Rick: NO PARENTS COULD
WATCH THESE SCENES WITHOUT
BEING SHAKEN TO THE CORE.
AND MANY DESCRIBE HORRIFIC
SCENES BEFORE THEIR EYES.
WE'LL SPEAK WITH ONE MOTHER
WHOSE DAUGHTER WAS INSIDE THE
SCHOOL DURING THE SHOOTING.
MAKE A WISH!
I WISH WE COULD
LIE HERE FOREVER.
I WISH THIS TEST DRIVE WAS OVER,
SO WE COULD HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
TEST DRIVE!
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A JETTA.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN,
$0 DUE AT SIGNING, $0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
Uh...
Um...
Hm...
Umm...
Uh...
Oh !
The Windows Phone 8X
by HTC on Verizon.
It features easy
to navigate live tiles
that are simple
to customize.
Just pin what matters most
right to your homescreen.
Exclusively with Data Sense--
a feature that makes the most
of you plan.
Only on Verizon.
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
>>  WE HAVE A FOX NEWS ALERT.
CONCERNING SECRETARY OF STATE
HILLARY CLINTON AND WE'RE
LEARNING THAT SECRETARY
CLINTON IS RECOVERING FROM A
CONCUSSION SHE SUSTAINED AFTER
SHE FAINTED EARLIER IN THE
WEEK AND LEARNING THAT MRS.
CLINTON WILL BE UNABLE TO
TESTIFY NEXT THURSDAY BEFORE
THE HOUSE AND SENATE PANEL ON
THE BENGHAZI ATTACK AND HAEG
HEALING FROM THE CONCUSSION
AND IN A STATEMENT THAT SAYS,
QUOTE, WHILE SUFFERING FROM A
STOMACH VIRUS, SECRETARY
CLINTON BECAME DIE HYDRATED
SUFFERING A CONCUSSION AND
SHE'S CONTINUING TO BE
MONITORED BY HER DOCTORS, END
QUOTE.
WISH HER THE BEST.
>> Jamie: AND ALSO, WELL, AS
WE REPORTED EARLIER THIS HOUR,
THERE ARE A LOT OF NEW DETAILS
EMERGING ABOUT THE HEROISM OF
TEACHERS AND FACULTY WHO
LITERALLY PUT THEMSELVES
BETWEEN THEMSELVES AND THE
GUNMAN AND BARRICADING
THEMSELVES.
AND A LIBRARIAN SAYS SHE HEARD
A SCUFFLE ON THE INTERCOM AND
CALLED THE OFFICE AND THE
SECRETARY TOLD HER AS THE
INCIDENT WAS GOING ON THERE'S
AN INCIDENT GOING ON IN THE
SCHOOL AND SHE HUDDLED WITH
STUDENTS IN A STORAGE ROOM
UNTIL THE POLICE ARRIVED AND
PARENTS RUSHED TO THE SCENE
HOPING AND PRAYING THAT THEIR
CHILD WAS ONE OF THE ONES THAT
SURVIVED.
MY NEXT GUEST'S EIGHT-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHTER ATTENDED SANDY
ELEMENTARY AND SURVIVED THE
SHOOTING.
AND BRENDA TELLS WHAT HER
CHILD EXPERIENCED.
WE'RE GRITFUL THAT YOUR
DAUGHTER SURVIVED AND ONLY
IMAGINE HOW YOUR HEART GOES
OUT TO THE OTHER PARENTS?
HOW ARE YOU DOING.
>> I'M NOT DOING WELL TODAY.
YESTERDAY I WAS RUNNING ON
ADRENALIN, I WAS HAPPY MY
DAUGHTER WAS ALIVE.
I WAS VERY SAD FOR THE REST OF
THE FAMILIES AND TODAY, IT
REALLY HIT ME BAD, REALLY BAD.
>> I'M SURE IT'S SOMETHING
THAT EVERY PARENT, I'M A
PARENT AS WELL, THINKS COULD
NEVER HAPPEN AT THEIR SCHOOL.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> Jamie: DO YOU KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT THIS SUSPECT?
>> I'D NEVER HEARD OF HIM.
I HAVE OLDER CHILDREN, 22 AND
17 AND THEY NEVER HEARD OF HIM
EITHER.
SO I--
AND I DIDN'T KNOW HIS MOTHER
EITH
EITHER.
>> HOW IS YOUR CHILD DOING
TODAY, YOUR DAUGHTER.
>> SHE'S BEEN DOING WELL AND
HER COUSIN IS HERE AND THEY'RE
PLAYING CHRISTMAS MUSIC AND
SHE'S UPBEAT AND TRYING TO
KEEP THINGS NORMAL.
>> Jamie: WE'RE GOING TO TALK
TO A PSYCHOLOGIST, YOU DON'T
HAVE TO HAVE HAD A CHILD AT
THAT SCHOOL TO TALK ABOUT
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
WHAT DID YOU SAY TO HER IN THE
LAST 24 HOURS.
>> LAST NIGHT AFTER WE DID
MANY INTERVIEWS AND IT WAS ALL
OVER AND WE HUDDLED ON THE
COUCH AND I SAID TO HER, I
WANT YOU TO UNDERSTAND THAT
THIS IS NOT SOMETHING THAT
HAPPENS EVERY DAY, THIS IS A
RARE OCCURRENCE AND YOU NEED
TO FEEL SAFE IN YOUR SCHOOL,
THIS SCHOOL IS GOING TO BE
SAFE.
AND THE TEACHERS ARE THERE,
AND 'CAUSE HER TEACHER, YOU
KNOW, SAVED HER LIFE BY
LOCKING THE DOOR AND PUTTING
THEM IN THE CORNER.
AND YOU KNOW, NOW, HEARING
MANY STORIES OF HEROISM BY
THESE TEACHERS AND ESPECIALLY
THE ONE THAT WAS KILLED AND
LOCKED HER KIDS IN THE
BATHROOM.
>> AND LINDA, TELL ME ABOUT
WHAT YOUR DAUGHTER DESCRIBES
HAVING SEEN AND I KNOW AS SOME
OF THE CHILDREN LEFT THE
SCHOOL, THE OFFICERS AND
AUTHORITIES THAT WERE THERE
TOLD THEM TO DO IT WITH THEIR
EYES CLOSED.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> WHAT HAS SHE TOLD YOU?
>> SOPHIA WAS TAKEN, ESCORTED
BY THE POLICE FROM HER
CLASSROOM, BUT THEY WENT
THROUGH A BACK ENTRANCE THAT
WAS NEAR THE PLAYGROUND SO
THEY DIDN'T NEED TO GO THROUGH
THE FRONT.
SHE SAID SHE SAW NOTHING AND
THEY WALKED ALONG THE
PLAYGROUND AND THE BASEBALL
FIELD TO THE FIREHOUSE, AND
THAT'S WHERE I CAUGHT UP WITH
HER AS SOON AS SHE GOT TO THE
FIREHOUSE.
>> WELL, IT'S A BLESSING THAT
SHE DID NOT HAVE TO EXPERIENCE
MORE THAN SHE ABLE DID, DO YOU
EXPECT THAT OVER TIME YOU'LL
NEED TO NOT ONLY GIVE HER THE
LOVE THAT YOU HAVE AND MOVE
FORWARD THE BEST YOU CAN, BUT
DO YOU EXPECT THAT SHE'LL NEED
MORE FROM YOU, HAVING GONE
THROUGH THIS?
>> YEAH, I THINK THAT ONCE SHE
NEEDS TO GO BACK TO SCHOOL,
WHICH I THINK WILL BE IN THE
BEGINNING OF THE NEW YEAR, I
THINK SHE'S GOING TO START
FEELING THE EFFECTS MORE.
RIGHT NOW, SHE'S -- SHE'S
HAPPY BECAUSE SHE HAS HER
FAMILY AROUND HER, IT'S
CHRISTMAS TIME.
BUT I THINK WHEN THE REALITY
HITS AND SHE HAS TO GO BACK
THERE, THAT'S WHEN I THINK
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO SEEK
COUNSELING.
>> Jamie: SHE'S EIGHT YEARS
OLD.
HAS SHE LOST ANY OF HER
FRIENDS AS A RESULT OF THIS?
DOES SHE KNOW OF ANY CHILDREN
SHE WAS CLOSE TO OR KNEW THAT
WERE NOT AS LUCKY AS SHE IS?
>> MY FEAR IS THAT THE
SIBLINGS OF THE CHILDREN IN
HER CLASS OR THE CHILDREN SHE
HAD IN PAST GRADES, THAT THEY
MAY HAVE BEEN AFFECTED.
I DON'T KNOW THE NAMES.
I TRIED WHEN I WAS IN THE HIRE
HOUSE TO SCAN THE ROOM AND SEE
WHO I KNOW AND THE CHILDREN
THAT I KNOW AND I DID SEE MANY
OF THEM, BUT I DON'T KNOW
ABOUT THEIR YOUNGER SIBLINGS
AND THAT'S WHAT'S BREAKING MY
HEART.
>> Jamie: AS THIS COMMUNITY
TRIES TO MOVE FORWARD AS WE'VE
TRAGICALLY SEEN IN OTHER
SITUATIONS LIKE AURORA, LIKE
COLUMBINE, WHAT CAN WE DO TO
HELP THE FOLKS THERE?
>> YOU, AS THE AMERICA?
>> AMERICA.
WE ALL CARE SO MUCH AND I'M
SINCERELY ASKING YOU WHAT WE
CAN DO?
>> I THINK YOU NEED TO KEEP US
ALL IN YOUR PRAYERS, EVEN
THOSE WHOSE BABIES SURVIVED,
THANK THE LORD AND ESPECIALLY
THOSE WHO LOST THEIR BABIES.
AND PERSONALLY, MY FEELING
THAT WE NEED TO DO SOMETHING
ABOUT GUN CONTROL IN THIS
COUNTRY BECAUSE IT'S HAPPENING
TOO OFTEN AND IT NEEDS TO
STOP.
>> I UNDERSTAND THAT THE
PRINCIPAL, WHO WAS QUITE
HEROIC HERSELF.
>> YES.
>> Jamie: HAD RECENTLY
INSTALLED AND BUMPED UP
SECURITY AT THE SCHOOL AND DO
YOU KNOW WHY SHE DID THAT AND
WERE THE PARENTS INVOLVED?
>> I DIDN'T HEAR ABOUT IT.
I JUST ALWAYS KNEW YOU NEEDED
TO BE BUZZED IN YOU NEED TO GO
INTO THE OFFICE WHICH WAS
DIRECTLY ACROSS FROM THE FRONT
DOOR, THEY COULD SEE WHO IS AT
THE DOOR, YOU HAD TO SIGN IN
IF YOU WERE A VISITOR, BECAUSE
I VOLUNTEERED AND EVEN IF THEY
KNEW YOU, YOU HAD TO SIGN IN
AT THE TIME YOU CAME IN AND AT
THE TIME YOU LEFT, YOU HAD TO
SIGN OUT.
AND THE SECRETARIES IN OFFICE
LOVED THEIR KIDS, VERY
PROTECTIVE.
ONE TIME I DIDN'T SIGN MY
DAUGHTER OUT WHEN I WAS TAKING
HER HOME AND I--
I GOT REPRIMANDED FOR THAT AND
IT NEVER HAPPENED AGAIN.
OF SO, THEY TOOK THE SECURITY
OF THE KIDS VERY, VERY
SERIOUSLY.
>> Jamie: BRENDA LEBINSKI
WHOSE EIGHT-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER
WAS IN THIS SCHOOL AND
EXPERIENCED THE TRAGEDY.
AS YOU MENTIONED, IT MAY GET
TOUGHER BEFORE IT GETS EASIER,
KNOW THAT WE'RE ALL THERE WITH
YOU IN YOUR HEARTS AND OUR
PRAYERS.
>> THANK YOU, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH FOR CARING ABOUT OUR
TOWN.
>> Jamie: WE REALLY DO, THANK
YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Jamie: RICK.
>> Rick: WELL, THE SHOOTING Y IE
ENTIRE COUNTRY MOURNING AS WE
SEARCH FOR ANSWERS AS TO HOW
SO MANY YOUNG LIVES, SO MANY
LIVES COULD BE TAKEN SO
QUICKLY.
COMING UP NEXT THE ROLE THAT
STATES CAN PLAY IN TIMES LIKE
THIS.