NOAH, CAROLINE, JESSICA,, ALLIS.
>> VERY TOUCHING TRIBUTE AND
INCOMING DAY ASKS WEEKS WE'LL
LEARN ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED IN
NEWTOWN, WE'RE ON THE GROUND
IN CONNECTICUT AND WILL BRING
YOU MORE RIGHT HERE ON THE
RECORD.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US
TONIGHT.
MAKE SURE YOU GO TO
GRETAWIRE.COM.
GOOD NIGHT FROM WASHINGTON.
♪
>> HELLO EVERYONE.
I AM DANA PERINO.
WELCOME TO THE FIVE.
IT HAS BEEN 48-HOURS SINCE THE
SHOOTING.
THE FIRST FUNERALS WERE HELD FOR
6-YEAR-OLD CLASSMATES NOAH
POZNER AND JACK PINTO HAS BEEN
LAID TO REST.
HE JOINS US NOW.
>> GOOD EVENING FROM SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
WE REMEMBER TWO OF THE YOUNGEST
VICTIMS TODAY.
YOU MENTIONED NOAH POZNER AGE 6.
HE JUST CELEBRATED A BIRTHDAY
ONLY A MONTH AGO ON
NOVEMBER 20TH.
HE WAS CONSIDERED A LIVELY AND
SMART KID.
THAT'S HOW HIS UNCLE DESCRIBED
HIM.
THAT WAS ONE OF TWO FUNERALS
TODAY.
GET THIS, DANA, NOAH HAD A TWIN
SISTER.
HER NAME WAS ARIEL.
SHE WAS IN THE SCHOOL AT THE
TIME OF THE SHOOTING BUT SHE WAS
IN A DIFFERENT CLASSROOM.
THESE TWO WERE SAID TO BE
INSEPERABLE IN LIFE.
ARIEL MADE IT OUT OKAY.
THE OTHER FUNERAL FOR YOUNG JACK
PINTO ALSO AGE 6 A HUGE
SPORTSMSPORTS
FAN A BIG NEW YORK GIANTS FAN.
HE WAS RECOGNIZED YESTERDAY BY
WIDE RECEIVER VICTOR CRUISE WHO
WROTE RIP JACK PINTO REST IN
PEACE ON HIS CLEATS ALSO JACK
PINTO MY HERO THE WORDS OF
VICTOR CRUISE THAT CONTACTED THE
FAMILY.
THERE'S LIKELY A MEETING BETWEEN
THAT FAMILY AND ONE OF HIS HEROS
IN LIFE VICTOR CRUISE.
HE LOVES SPORTS, BASKETBALL,
BASEBALL, WRESTLING.
IN A FAMILY STATEMENT LATE TODAY
THEY SAID A JOY WHOSE WIDE REACH
BEE LIED HIS SIX SHORT YEARS.
>> THE FUNERALS THROUGH OUT THE
WEEK THERE WILL BE MANY MORE
LIVES TO REMEMBER THEN.
AS FOR THE INVESTIGATION AND THE
SCHOOL BEHIND ME WE ARE AT THE
POINT WHERE IT'S ABOUT AS CLOSE
AS YOU CAN GET TO THE SCHOOL
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
IT'S ABOUT 100 YARDS DOWN
DICKINSON ROAD BEHIND THE
FIREHOUSE.
POLICE ARE TELLING ME IT IS
CONSIDERED A CRIME SCENE UNTIL
FURTHER NOTICE.
THERE IS NO TELLING WHEN AND IF
THIS SCHOOL MAY OPEN AGAIN.
WE SAW SEVERAL MOVING VANS GO
DOWN THE DRIVEWAY AND LEAVE WITH
ENTIRE 18-WHEELERS LOADED WITH
DESKS AND CHAIRS.
THEY HAVE BEEN MOVED TO A
BUILDING ABOUT 7 MILES DOWN THE
ROAD WHERE THEY ARE NOW STARTING
TO SET UP A TEMPORARY SCHOOL.
WHEN THAT SCHOOL OPENS IT IS NOT
CLEAR BECAUSE CHRISTMAS STARTS A
WEEK FROM TOMORROW.
WE ARE WAITING FOR MORE NEWS ON
THAT.
AS FOR THE INVESTIGATION WE WOKE
UP TO SOME GRIMM NEWS EARLIER
TODAY YET AGAIN POLICE
CONFIRMING THE MOTHER WAS SHOT
FOUR TIMES IN THE HEAD WHILE SHE
LAY IN BED FRIDAY MORNING STILL
WEARING HER PAJAMAS.
NANCY LANZA AGE 52 THE KILLER'S
MOTHER DEAD ON THE SCENE THERE.
WE ARE TOLD FIRST RESPONDERS
PERHAPS SAVED MANY, MANY MORE
LIVES.
POLICE BELIEVE THAT THE SIRENS
THE FIRST RESPONDERS THE POLICE
ON SCENE ALERTED THE SHOOTER
THAT GOT HIM TO SHOP SHOOTING
AND TURN THE GUN ON HIMSELF.
THEY FOUND HUNDREDS OF ROUNDS OF
AMMUNITION THAT WERE UNUSED ON
HIS POSSESSION OR NEARBY THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL BEHIND US.
AS FOR THE CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR
WE FOUND OUT LAST HOUR FRIDAY
MORNING AT 9:30 A.M. WHEN THE
KILLING BEGAN.
ALL OF THE CHURCHES ACROSS
CONNECTICUT TO PEEL THE BELLS
FOR THE MOMENT OF CENTER LINES.
HE'S ASKING THE GOVERNOR'S
ASSOCIATION.
IT'S QUITE POSSIBLE WE WILL HAVE
A NATIONAL MOMENT OF CENTER
LINES AT 9:30 A.M. EASTERN TIME
THE MOMENT WE BELIEVE THE KILLER
GAINED ACCESS INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
>> BILL HEMMER WHO HAS BEEN AN
AMAZINGLY REASSURING VOICE OF
EXCELLENT REPORTING.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR JOINING
US.
LET'S START OUR SHOW TONIGHT
WITH GENERAL REFLECTIONS.
AS A FATHER AND A PROUD AMERICAN
WHO LOVES KIDS ESPECIALLY A
6-YEAR-OLD WHO DOESN'T LOVE A
6-YEAR-OLD THAT WONDERFUL SPIRIT
AND INNOCENCE.
WHAT A HEART WRENCHING FEW DAYS
THIS HAS BEEN.
WHEN YOU START HEARING SOME OF
THESE STORIES AND YOU LEARN A
LITTLE BIT MORE ABOUT THEM.
IT ALMOST DOES HELP YOU START TO
PUT IT IN PERSPECTIVE AND HEAL A
BIT MORE.
>> SURE.
>> THE THING ABOUT THIS ONE,
AGAIN THE DAY AFTER THE
COLORADO, AURORA COLORADO
SHOOTING WE WENT THROUGH THIS.
WE PUT IT OUT THERE AND THE NEXT
DAY IS THE DAY WE STARTED
LOOKING AT THE VICTIMS.
WE HAVE BEEN PUSHING ALL MORNING
TO STAY ON THE VICTIMS.
I DON'T WANT TO TALK ABOUT THE
PERPETRATOR.
THE MOST IMPORTANT THING IS THIS
IS NEW TOWN CONNECTICUT.
WE DROP OUR KINDERGARTNERS
6-YEAR-OLDS, 14-YEAR-OLDS AT
SCHOOL AND WE SAY GOOD-BYE WE
TRUST THEIR GOING TO COME HOME.
FOR 20 FAMILIES THIS WEEKEND
THEY WEREN'T ABLE TO PICK THEM
UP.
THERE WILL BE PLENTY OF TIME FOR
REFLECTION ON WHAT WENT WRONG WE
MAKE SURE IT DOESN'T HAPPEN
AGAIN OR TO OUR BEST ABILITY IT
DOESN'T HAPPEN.
FOR NOW FOR ME THE MOST
IMPORTANT PART OF THIS IS THE 20
YOUNG ANGELS THAT WE LOST THIS
WEEKEND.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA SAYING FRIDAY
WAS THE MOST DIFFICULT DAY OF
HIS PRESIDENCY.
LAST NIGHT HE ADDRESSED THE
COMMUNITY BECAUSE EVERYBODY HAD
A CHANCE TO SEE THAT LIVE.
ONE OF THE THINGS YOU PICKED OUT
WAS THE END IF WE COULD GET THE
REACTION TO THE PRESIDENT'S
SPEECH LAST NIGHT.
>> CHARLOTTE, DANIEL, OLIVIA,
JOSEPHINE, ANNA, DYLAN,
MADELEINE, KATHERINCATH KRAS R-
CHASE, JESSE, JAMES, GRACE,
EMILY, JACK, NOAH, CAROLINE,
JESSICA, BENJAMIN, AVIELLE,
ALLISON.
GOD HAS CALLED THEM ALL HOME.
>> I THOUGHT THAT WAS AN AMAZING
WAY TO END THE SPEECH LAST
NIGHT.
>> I THINK IT WAS EXACTLY THE
RIGHT THING TO DO.
I AGREE WITH ERIC.
THE OTHER VICTIMS HERE ARE THE
OTHER KIDS IN THAT SCHOOL WHO
WITNESSED ALL OF THIS AND ARE
GOING TO HAVE YEARS OF TRAUMA IN
FRONT OF THEM.
ONE OF THE THINGS I HAVE A
DIFFICULT TIME UNDERSTANDING IS
WHY THEY NEED TO BE INTERVIEWED
AT THAT AGE.
AUTHORITIES THINK THAT THEY DO.
I THINK PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS BEEN
TOO FAR TOO MANY OF THESE IN HIS
FOUR YEARS IN OFFICE.
I THINK HE DID A GOOD JOB.
FOR THAT TOWN I CAN'T IMAGE.
IT IS UNIMAGINABLE BEING A
FATHERMENT YOUR GREATEST NICE
MARE IS TO HAVE POLICE KNOCK ON
YOUR DOOR AND SAY YOUR KID
SCRATCHED HIS CAR OR SOMETHING
LIKE THAT, 20 KIDS.
>> AND IT COULD HAVE BEEN MUCH
WORSE.
AS BILL WAS SAYING, KIMBERLY,
ONE OF THE THINGS YOU WANTED TO
POINT OUT WAS THE HEROISM.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT THE SOUND
BITE YOU CHOOSE.
>> TOLD ME GOOD MORNING AND
ASKED HOW I WAS DOING.
I SAID I WAS DOING WELL.
SHE SAID SHE LOVED ME I GAVE HER
A KISS AND I WAS OUT THE DOOR.
MY DAUGHTER EMILY WOULD BE ONE
OF THE FIRST ONES TO BE STANDING
AND GIVING HER LOVE AND SUPPORT
TO ALL OF THOSE VICTIMS, BECAUSE
THAT'S THE TYPE OF PERSON SHE
IS.
>> KIMBERLY, I CAN IMAGE HOW
HARD IT WAS AS A PARENT OF A
6-YEAR-OLD.
TELL US YOUR THOUGHTS.
>> TAKING MY LITTLE BOY TO
SCHOOL EVERY DAY, HE'S SO YOUNG
I STILL CALL HIM MY BABY BECAUSE
CHILDREN ARE SO INNOCENT THEY
RELY ON YOU LOOK UP TO YOU TO
KEEP THEM SAFE.
WHEN YOU DROP THEM OFF EVERY
DAY, BEING A PROSECUTOR AND
FORMER TEACHER MYSELF OF
CHILDREN IN KINDERGARTEN AND
FIRST GRADE I LOOK AT HIS FACE
IT'S THE LAST TIME I AM GOING TO
SEE IT.
I PRESSURE HIM SO MUCH.
I MEMORIZE THE CLOTHES HE HAS ON
HIS LITTLE SHIRT HIS JACKET HIS
SHOES, HIS BACKPACK.
I WANT TO HOLD THAT MOMENT SO I
DON'T TAKE IT FOR GRANTED.
IMAGE THE PARENTS WHO DID THAT
ON THAT MORNING NOT KNOWING THE
UNSPEAKABLE TRAGEDY THAT WOULD
HAPPEN AT THE END OF THE DAY
THAT'S THE LAST MOMENT THEY HAD
WITH THEIR CHILDREN.
TO PICK THEM UP ON A FRIDAY AT A
TIME RIGHT BEFORE THE HOLIDAYS
IT'S UNBEARABLE.
>> JOINING US NOW TODAY WE HAVE
BRIAN KILMEADE WHICH IS GOOD.
THIS MORNING SOME OF THE STORIES
WE TOLD HERE OBVIOUSLY THE HEART
WRENCHING ONE FROM KIMBERLY YOU
TALKED A LOT ABOUT THOSE THIS
MORNING ON FOX AND FRIENDS.
WHAT STUCK OUT FOR YOU?
HOW DO YOU DECIDE TO TELL THE
STORY?
>> YOUR STORIES ARE JUST AS
IMPORTANT BUT WHAT STOOD OUT FOR
ME IS WHAT THE TEACHERS DID AND
THE PRINCIPAL DID.
I UNDERSTAND NAVY SEALS ARE
TRAINED TO ACT LIKE THIS.
I STILL AM IN AWE HOW THEY ACT
UNDER PRESSURE AND PUT THEIR
WELFARE ASIDE FOR SOMEBODY ELSE.
WHEN YOU HAVE A 27-YEAR-OLD
TEACHER WHO HAS NEVER BEEN SHOT
AT BEFORE YOU IMAGE SEEING A
BUNCH OF FIRST GRADERS HIDING IN
THE CLOSET.
A CLASS HAS BEEN WIPED OUT
ACROSS THE HALL.
THAT GUNMAN COMES INTO HER
CLASSROOM AND SHE HAS HER KIDS
HIDING IN THE CLOSET SHE TELLS
THE GUNMAN GO DOWN TO THE HALL.
WHERE ARE THE KIDS?
THE KIDS ARE DOWN IN THE
AUDITORIUM.
ALL OF A SUDDEN SIX KIDS PANIC
AND THEY RUN OUT OF THE CLOSET
AT WHICH TIME ACCORDING TO
REPORTS SHE DIVES IN FRONT OF
THOSE KIDS TAKES THEIR BULLETS.
THE KIDS ALSO LOSE THEIR LIVES.
ONE OF THOSE KIDS WAS BURIED
TODAY.
WHERE DID THAT COME FROM THE
HEROISM.
WHERE THAT COMES FROM AS A
TEACHER IS PURE INSTINCT,
FEARLESSNESS.
THE PRINCIPAL THERE'S A GUNMAN
IN THE HALL.
THEY DON'T RUN THEY RUN AT THE
GUNMAN.
>> IT'S AMAZING THE AMOUNT OF
COURAGE.
>> AWE INSPIRING.
>> ALSO SPEAKING OF THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA HAD I THOUGHT A
GREAT WAY TO DESCRIBE THE SCENE
FOR US.
YOU CAN IMAGE A 6-YEAR-OLD
SAYING THIS ABOUT HOW HE WAS
GOING TO HELP EVERYBODY GET OUT
OF IT.
LISTEN.
>> THERE WERE THE SCENES OF THE
SCHOOL CHILDREN HELPING ONE
ANOTHER, HOLDING EACH OTHER,
DUTIFULLY FOLLOWING INSTRUCTIONS
IN THE WAY THAT YOUNG CHILDREN
SOMETIMES DO.
ONE CHILD EVEN TRYING TO
ENCOURAGE A GROWN-UP BY SAYING,
I KNOW KARATE SO IT'S OKAY.
I WILL LEAD THE WAY OUT.
>> I LOVE THAT STORY.
I THOUGHT ABOUT, ERIC, HOW WE
ALL HAD -- IF YOU HAVE A CHILD
IN YOUR LIFE OR YOU ARE FAMILIAR
WITH A 6-YEAR-OLD'S THINKING,
YOU TAKE WHAT BRIAN SAID ABOUT
COURAGE AND SOMETHING ABOUT THE
INNOCENCE OF A 6-YEAR-OLD, WHAT
DO YOU TAKE AWAY FROM THAT?
>> BRIAN SAID SOMETHING VERY
IMPORTANT.
TEACHERS AREN'T TRAINED MOST OF
THEM AREN'T TRAINED TO DO THIS.
THEY ARE NOT TRAINED TO RUN
TOWARDS THE FIRE, TOWARDS THE
BAD GUYS.
THESE TEACHERS DID.
IT STRIKES ME A LOT OF TIMES
SOME OF US ARE HARD ON TEACHERS
WE ARE TOUGH ON THEM FOR A LOT
OF REASONS.
THIS IS JUST AN AWAKENING TO A
GUY LIKE ME WHO SAYS THESE
TEACHERS ARE DOING GOD'S WORK.
THEY ARE PROTECTING OUR MOST
VALUABLE PRIZED ASSETS AND DOING
THINGS LIKE THAT.
I HAVE TO THINK MOST EVERY
TEACHER IN THAT SITUATION WOULD
PROBABLY DO THE SAME THING.
>> I WANT TO GET THAT YOOUGHTS
BOB AND BRIAN.
WHAT DID YOUR KIDS ASK ABOUT
THIS WEEKEND.
THEY ARE OLDER.
>> THEY ARE OLDER.
THEY HAD A HARD TIME.
THEY SAID PLEASE EXPLAIN TO ME
HOW THIS HAPPENED.
THEY ARE BAD PEOPLE.
THEY TALK ABOUT FATE AND HOW DID
GOD LET THIS HAPPEN.
I THINK THEY WERE JUST STUNNED.
THIS IS WHAT KIMBERLY SAID.
IMMEDIATELY TOOK OUT MY PHOTO
ALBUM.
SAW MY KIDS WHEN THEY WERE THIS
AGE.
I JUST -- IT IS SO UNIMAGINABLE.
BY THE WAY ERIC I GIVE YOU
CREDIT WE DO GET A PROPENSITY TO
GET DOWN.
THEY SHOWED ENORMOUS COURAGE.
I UNDERSTAND A PARENT THROWING
THEMSELVES IN FRONT OF BULLETS.
WE COULD DO THAT.
BUT FOR A TEACHER TO DO THAT FOR
KIDS THAT WERE NOT MER BLOHER B
REALLY IS AN EXTRAORDINARY
CIRCUMSTANCE.
>> MY OLDER SON 11TH GRADE HE
SAID IS IT POSSIBLE TO GET A
PSYCHOLOGICAL EVALUATION OF
THESE KIDS BEFORE?
600 KIDS IN YOUR CLASS 600 KIDS
IN YOUR CLASSES HOW DO YOU GET
AN EVALUATION TO SEE WHAT THEY
ARE CAPABLE OF.
FOR MY 9 AND 11-YEAR-OLD.
MY 11-YEAR-OLD WATCHED AND
WALKED AWAY.
I TRIED TO CHANGE THE CHANNEL
BUT I SEE ON THE NEXT DAY I HAD
TO KEEP THEM GOING BECAUSE THEY
WERE UPDATED.
MY 9-YEAR-OLD SAID DO YOU THINK
SOMETHING LIKE THAT WOULD EVER
HAPPEN IN OUR SCHOOL.
I SAID YOU KNOW WHAT LOOK FOR
THEM TO DRILL ON MONDAY BECAUSE
I KNOW IN MY HEAD IT CAN
ABSOLUTELY HAPPEN.
YOU HAVE A GREAT LADY IN HER 60s
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO IS SIGN YOUR
NAME AND YOU CAN WALK RIGHT INTO
AT THAT SCHOOL.
>> WE ARE GOING TO TALK ABOUT
WHAT SOME OF THE EXPERTS
SUGGESTED IF YOU ARE A PARENT AT
HOME WHAT YOU SHOULD TALK TO
THEM ABOUT.
WE ARE GOING TO KEEP ON THIS.
DIRECTLY AHEAD YOU WILL HEAR
FROM THE PARENTS OF JESSICA
REKOS ONE OF THE YOUNG CHILDREN
WHO WERE KILLED.
PLEASE STAY WITH US.
♪
>> WELCOME BACK EVERYBODY.
I DROVE MY SON TO SCHOOL THIS
MORNING WE TALKED MORE ABOUT THE
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT.
SOMETHING I FELT WAS NECESSARY
BEFORE SENDING HIM OFF TO SCHOOL
IN A SAFE PLACE.
IT'S GOOD TO TALK ABOUT THESE
THINGS IN MY OPINION.
HE GOT OUT OF THE CAR I RECALL
LOOKING BACK TO SEE WHAT
SNEAKERS HE WAS WEARING.
I HAVE NO IDEA WHY I DID THAT.
I REMEMBER DOING IT.
WHEN I HEARD THIS A LITTLE WHILE
LATER IT SENT CHILLS THROUGH OUT
MY BODY.
LISTEN.
>> I KNOW EXACTLY WHAT SHE WAS
WEARING.
I KNEW I WOULD SEE HER PONY TAIL
COME AROUND THE CORNER AND HER
JACKET AND HER BLACK GLITTERY
SHOES SHE HAD ON THIS MORNING.
I KNEW I WAS GOING TO SEE HER.
>> THERE WAS STILL HOPE.
>> HOPE.
>> THE CHILDREN WERE HIDING.
>> FINALLY AROUND 1:15 THEY SAID
IT WAS A TRAGIC DAY IN NEWTOWN
TODAY 20 CHILDREN WERE KILLED.
AND -- DON'T TELL ME MY LITERAL
GIRL IS GONE.
>> I JUST POINT BLANK FOUND A
STATE TROOPER AND WAS LIKE ARE
THERE ANY SURVIVORS.
ARE YOU TELLING ME THAT STANDING
HERE AS A PARENT MY CHILD IS
GONE.
HE SAID, YES.
>> BLUE TRIPLE DARK BLUE JEANS
ABERCROMBIE JACKET.
THE LEAP OF FAITH WHEN WE PUT
OUR LITTLE ONES OFF INTO THE
SCHOOLS.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
MOST TIMES THEY COME HOME SAFE
AND SOUND.
>> IT IS SO CHALLENGING, YOU
REALLY ARE TURNING OVER YOUR
PRIDE YOUR HEART YOUR VOW EVERY
MORNING TO THE PEOPLE AT THE
SCHOOL.
I HAVE BEEN ON BOTH SIDES AS A
MOTHER OF A 6-YEAR-OLD AND AS A
TEACHER HAVING WORKED WITH A
TEACHER WITH SPECIAL NEEDS
CHILDREN, THE EMOTIONAL
DEVELOPMENTAL CHALLENGES.
THAT'S SOMEBODY'S CHILD.
THAT'S THEIR LIFE.
SO IMPORTANT.
WHEN YOU TURN YOUR KID OVER YOU
ARE HOPING THINGS ARE GOING TO
WORK OUT.
YOUR CHILD ISN'T GOING TO GET
BULLIED THEY ARE WELL ENOUGH TO
GO TO SCHOOL.
THEY ARE GOING TO GET THE
EDUCATION THEY DESERVE BUT MY
GOD THEY ARE GOING TO COME HOME
AT THE END OF THE DAY TO HAVE A
SNACK TO DO THEIR HOMEWORK.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID BEING A
PARENT IS LIKE HAVING YOUR HEART
ON THE OUTSIDE OF YOUR BODY FOR
THE REST OF YOUR LIFE.
I DON'T HAVE CHILDREN ALTHOUGH I
AM A STEP GRANDMOTHER OF
6-YEAR-OLD TWINS A BOY AND A
GIRL WHEN BILL HEMMER WAS
REPORTING ABOUT NOAH WHO DIED
AND HIS SISTER ARIEL YOU THINK
OF THEM.
THIS AMAZING COMMUNITY OBVIOUSLY
VERY CLOSE YOU LOOK AT HOW MANY
PEOPLE TURNED OUT LAST NIGHT.
IN FACT ED HENRY REPORTED THAT
HE TALK TO DO SOMEBODY WHO WAS
ON THEIR WAY TO SEE PRESIDENT
OBAMA ADDRESS THE GATHERING.
THEY HAD WALKED TWO-MILES
BECAUSE THAT WAS THE NEAREST
PARKING PLACE.
IT WAS NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT BUT
IT COULD HAVE BEEN ANYWHERE.
THEN ONE OF THE THINGS WE ALL
WANT AS HUMANS IS A DEFINITIVE
ANSWER AS TO WHY, WHAT ARE WE
GOING TO DO ABOUT IT WE ARE
GOING TO FIX IT AND EVERYTHING
WILL BE OKAY.
IT IS IMPORTANT TO TELL KIDS WE
DON'T HAVE ALL OF THE ANSWERS.
>> A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE SAYING
VIRGINIA TECH THERE WERE MORE
FATALITIES IN VIRGINIA TECH.
VIRGINIA TECH PEOPLE CAME FROM
AROUND THE COUNTRY.
THIS IS ONE COMMUNITY ONE TOWN,
ALL AT ONCE.
>> IT IS.
I THINK EVERYONE IS TRYING TO
LEARN FROM IT.
THEY SAY IF THIS IDEALIC TOWN A
TOWN YOU WANT TO MOVE TO ASPIRE
TO IT CAN HAPPEN THERE WITH NO
HISTORY OF GUN VIOLENCE NO
HISTORY OF CENTER LINES, PERIOD
IT CAN HAPPEN ANYWHERE.  TAIT'S
NOT A THEORY.
IT CAN HAPPEN ANYWHERE.
EARLIER TODAY ON KILMEADE AND
FRIENDS HAD A HEART AND A TARGET
MADE IT SIMILAR TO 9-11.
WE KNOW WE ARE NOT TERROR PROOF
BUT WE TRY TO MAKE OURSELVES
TERROR PROOF AS BEST WE CAN.
THE QUESTION IS HOW DO YOU DO
THAT IN THE SCHOOL WITHOUT
BLOWING THE BUDGET.
I AM WONDERING BO DEEDLE BROUGHT
UP IN THE SHOW THERE'S SO MANY
RETIRED COPS AT 40.
IF YOU COULD PUT A PLAIN CLOTHED
PERSON WHO IS TRAINED WITH A
WEAPON SHOULD A PSYCHO PATH LIKE
THIS GET LOSE YOU COULD GO TO
WORK AND DO WHAT YOU HAVE TO DO
KNOWING YOU DID EVERYTHING YOU
CAN TO KEEP YOUR CHILD SAFE.
IF THEY WOULD BE TRAINED TO DO
IT UNALARMING AND IN THE PRIME
OF THEIR LIFE IN THEIR 40s THEY
ARE ALMOST GIVING BACK TO THEIR
COMMUNITY WITHOUT BLOWING THE
BUDGET I BELIEVE THAT WOULD GO A
LONG WAY.
>> I GREW UP IN CONNECTICUT.
I HAVE BEEN IN NEWTOWN MANY
TIMES.
IT IS THE ONE TOWN OF ALL OF THE
TOWNS IN CONNECTICUT I NEVER
WOULD HAVE EXPECTED IT TO
HAPPEN.
THEY CALL IT THE SAFEST TOWN IN
AMERICA I THINK 6TH OR 7TH
STATE.
IT DOES TAKE THE INNOCENCE AWAY
FROM ALL OF IT.
THIS WAS NOT A CITY WITH URBAN
PROBLEMS OR THE REST OF IT.
THIS IS AN IDEALIC LITTLE TOWN.
IMAGE IT'S NOT THAT BIG A TOWN.
JUST IMAGE CHRISTMAS.
IT IS VERY, VERY DIFFICULT.
>> -- SURVIVOR'S GUILT IS HUGE.
>> WE ARE UP AGAINST A BREAK
HERE.
WE ARE GOING TO TALK ABOUT OTHER
FACETS OF THE STORY.
ONE THING THAT IS IMPORTANT TO
NOTE.
WE PROTECT -- THINK ABOUT EVERY
SIPPING EL BANK YOU HAVE EVER
BEEN TO.
TELL ME ONE TIME YOU SEE A BANK
WHERE IT IS NOT GUARDED WITH
SOMEONE WITH OR WITHOUT A GUN
SOMEBODY WHO KNOWS WHAT THEY ARE
DOING.
YOU SHOW ME A BANK WITHOUT A
GUARD I WILL SHOW YOU THE BANK
THAT IS NOT GOING TO GET R-- I
SHOW YOU THE BANK THAT WILL GET
ROBBED.
PUT SOMEONE WHO KNOWS HOW TO
HANDLE HIMSELF AND A WEAPON AT
THE DOOR OF ANY SCHOOL IN
AMERICA.
IF WE CAN DO IT FOR BANKS WE CAN
DO IT AT A SCHOOL.
I WISH EVERY 20 ONE OF THESE
PARENTS WOULD GIVE A DIME FOR
THIS.
>> AS SOON AS HE SAW A COP, IF
WE GOT THERE EARLY ERROR SOONER.
>> GOT THERE 10 MINUTES BEFORE
THEY LOCKED THE SCHOOL DOWN,
TOO.
>> IF THEY HAVE SECURITY IN
THERE IT IS GOING TO SAVE LIVES.
>> WE HAVE TO GO.
WE MAY NEVER KNOW, I AM NOT
GOING TO USE HIS NAME.
THE SHOOTER WHY HE DID THIS
UNSPEAKABLE CRIME.
PEOPLE ARE TRYING TO FIGURE THIS
OUT.
CHARLES KRAUTHAMMER WHO WAS ONCE
A PSYCHOLOGIST HAS SOME
THOUGHTS.
>> Announcer: 'TIS THE SEASON
OF MORE--
MORE SHOPPING,
MORE DINING OUT...
AND ALONG WITH IT,
MORE IDENTITY THEFT.
BY THE TIME THIS HOLIDAY SEASON
IS OVER, AN ESTIMATED
1.2 MILLION IDENTITIES
MAY BE STOLEN.
EVERY TIME YOU PULL OUT YOUR
WALLET, SHOP ONLINE OR HIT THE
ROAD, YOU GIVE THIEVES A CHANCE
TO RUIN YOUR HOLIDAY.
BY THE TIME YOU'RE DONE WATCHING
THIS, AS MANY AS 40 MORE
IDENTITIES MAY BE STOLEN.
YOU CAN'T BE ON THE LOOKOUT
24/7, BUT LIFELOCK CAN.
THEY'RE RELENTLESS ABOUT
PROTECTING YOUR IDENTITY
EVERY MINUTE OF EVERY DAY.
WHEN SOMEONE TRIES TO TAKE OVER
YOUR BANK ACCOUNTS, DRAIN THE
EQUITY IN YOUR HOME, OR EVEN
TRIES TO BUY A CAR IN YOUR NAME,
LIFELOCK IS ON GUARD.
AND WITH LIFELOCK'S 24/7 ALERTS,
THEY CONTACT YOU BY TEXT,
PHONE OR EMAIL AS SOON AS THEY
DETECT SUSPICIOUS ACTIVITY
IN THEIR NETWORK.
LIFELOCK WANTS YOU TO BE
PROTECTED THIS HOLIDAY SEASON,
SO THEY'RE GIVING YOU 60 DAYS
OF PROTECTION RISK-FREE.
>> MY YEARS AS A PROSECUTOR
TAUGHT ME THAT YOU HAVE TO BE
PROACTIVE TO PROTECT YOURSELF
FROM CRIME,
AND THAT'S ESPECIALLY TRUE
OF IDENTITY THEFT.
THAT'S WHY I'M A MEMBER
OF LIFELOCK.
>> Announcer: ABSOLUTELY NO ONE
PROTECTS YOU BETTER THAN
LIFELOCK, AND THEY STAND BEHIND
THEIR PROTECTION WITH THE POWER
OF THEIR $1 MILLION
SERVICE GUARANTEE.
IN FACT, LAST YEAR, LIFELOCK
PROTECTED OVER TWO MILLION
PEOPLE DURING THE HOLIDAYS.
AND NOW THEY CAN DO IT FOR YOU.
TRY LIFELOCK'S PROTECTION
60 DAYS RISK-FREE.
CALL THE NUMBER ON YOUR SCREEN
OR GO TO LIFELOCK.COM/HOLIDAYS.
IT ONLY TAKES MINUTES
TO SIGN UP.
USE PROMO CODE: HOLIDAYS.
ORDER NOW AND GET A SPECIAL
HOLIDAY GIFT: A DOCUMENT
SHREDDER TO KEEP SENSITIVE
DOCUMENTS OUT OF THE WRONG
HANDS... A $29 VALUE, FREE!
CALL THE NUMBER ON YOUR SCREEN
OR GO ONLINE AND LET LIFELOCK
PROTECT YOUR IDENTITY FOR
60 DAYS RISK-FREE.
BECAUSE DURING THE HOLIDAYS,
KEEPING YOUR IDENTITY PROTECTED
MEANS KEEPING YOUR
FAMILY PROTECTED.
>> WELCOME BACK.
POLICE HAVE NOT YET RELEASED
DETAILS ABOUT THE MOTIVE OR
MENTAL STATE OF THE GUNMAN ADAM
LANZA.
IT IS IMPOSSIBLE TO KNOW EXACTLY
WHAT HAPPENED AND WHY.
CHARLES KRAUTHAMMER HAS THOUGHTS
ON WHAT THE FOCUS SHOULD BE.
>> YOU HAVE THE PSYCHOLOGIST THE
SHOOTER YOU HAVE A WEAPON AND
CULTURAL ENVIRONMENT.
I TEND TO GRAVITATE TOWARD THE
PSYCHOLOGY OF THE KILLER.
WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT THE DETAILS
OF THE CRIME HE BEGAN BY
SHOOTING HIS MOTHER IN THE FACE.
THAT I THINK IS WHERE I WOULD
START.
ALTHOUGH I THINK ALL OF THE
ISSUES HAVE TO BE DISCUSSED.
>> WHEN YOU GO THROUGH THE
DETAILS AND TRY TO MAKE SENSE OF
WHAT HAPPENED IN SOME KIND OF
DESPERATE HOPE FROM TRYING TO
STOP IT FROM HAPPENING AGAIN.
IT'S A NECESSARY PROCESS TO GO
THROUGH TO TRY TO FIGURE OUT WHY
THIS HAPPENED, WHAT WENT WRONG.
FOR ALL INTENTS AND PURPOSES THE
MOTHER WAS VERY DEVOTED REALLY
TRYING TO ATTEND TO HER SON TO
FOCUS ON DEVELOPMENTAL NEEDS AND
CHALLENGES EVEN BROUGHT HIM OUT
HOME SCHOOLED TO PUT HIM IN A
MORE COMFORTABLE ENVIRONMENT
BECAUSE HE FACED SOCIAL
CHALLENGES.
WHAT HAPPENED.
EVERYONE WANTS TO KNOW.
>> I GRAVITATE TO WANT WILL
{SUFFIXÑ]LING TO KNOW THAT, TOO.
THE POLICY QUESTION ABOUT GUNS
AND MAYBE EVEN MENTAL HEALTH I
THINK WILL BE A PART OF WHATEVER
PRESIDENT OBAMA DECIDES TO GO
FORWARD WITH.
THE THING THE ARTICLE THAT WENT
AROUND RETWEETED A NUMBER OF
TIMES.
SHE WAS A MOTHER SHE SAID I AM
ADAM LANZA'S MOTHER.
SHE DESCRIBED IN HEARTBREAKING
DETAIL WHAT IT WAS LIKE TO HAVE
A CHILD JUST WHAT SHE SAID BASED
ON DESCRIPTION SEEMED MAYBE
GOING IN THE SAME DIRECTION AS
THIS OTHER CHILD -- NOT CHILD
BUT THE KILLER I SHOULD SAY CH
HE WAS A SON AND THERE WAS A
DEVOTED MOTHER.
YOU THINK THERE MIGHT BE A LOT
OF PARENTS WHO ARE THINKING WHAT
CAN I DO?
WHAT SHOULD I DO?
DID HE HAVE EVERYTHING HE
NEEDED.
OBVIOUSLY NOT OR MAYBE THERE IS
JUST NO SIM TELL ANSWER TO THIS
QUESTION.
CHARLES IS SOMEBODY THAT I WOULD
TURN TO TO SAY HELP ME
UNDERSTAND THE PSYCHOLOGY BEHIND
THIS.
>> ERIC?
>> THAT PEAIECE IS AMAZING.
A MOM ON A BLOG SPOT I PULLED IT
UP IT HAD A THOUSANDS COMMENTS.
HERE'S THE THING.
THERE ARE SO MANY THEORIES
PEOPLE ARE GOING TO BLAME GUNS
AND MENTAL HEALTH AND VIDEO
GAMES AND RELIGION, BREAKDOWN IN
FAMILY.
WE NEED TO POINT SOMETHING OUT.
THERE WAS SO MUCH MISINFORMATION
THAT WAS PUT OUT THERE THERE WAS
A SECOND SHOOTER, THE SHOOTER
KILLED HIS FATHER FIRST.
THAT THE MOTHER WAS IN AT THE
SCHOOL.
WE NEED TO TAKE A BREATH LET THE
POLICE TO THEIR WORK PUT OUT THE
DETAILS WHETHER OR NOT THERE IS
MENTAL ISSUES THEN WE CAN START
TO ASSIST.
>> EVERYBODY NEEDS TO SOLVE THIS
PROBLEM.
THERE WILL BE A DAY FOR THAT
JUST FOR ME NOT YET.
>> IT IS TRUE THE HIGH SCHOOL
WHERE HE WENT SCHOOL MEMBERS THE
STAFF TEACHERS COUNSELORS
SECURITY PEOPLE MONITORED THIS
GUY BECAUSE HE HAD A SERIES OF
OBVIOUS PROBLEMS.
ONE OF THE THINGS WE KNOW ABOUT
THE PEOPLE WHO HAVE COMMITTED
THESE KINDS OF HEINOUS CRIMES
OVER THE LAST FEW YEARS ALL HAVE
HAD MENTAL PROBLEMS AT ONE TIME
OR ANOTHER.
IT IS PROBABLY SAFE TO SAY A
SANE PERSON WOULD NOT DO THIS.
THE QUESTION IS IN A STATE LIKE
CONNECTICUT WHERE THE GOVERNOR
ADMITTED THEY CUT BACK SERIOUSLY
ON MENTAL HEALTH COUNSELING AND
THEIR BUDGETS THE QUESTION IS,
THAT IS A LEGITIMATE QUESTION
PUBLIC POLICY QUESTION IS ARE WE
PUTTING OUR ASSETS IN THE WRONG
PLACE.
THIS GUY NOT JUST MONITOR HIM
BUT SHOULD HE HAVE HAD
COUNSELING?
>> OR IN A SPECIAL HOME.
HE WAS GETTING COUNSELING.
>> I AM NOT AS SMART AS CHARLES
KRAUTHAMMER BUT I WILL SAY THIS.
HE KNEW HOW TO SMASH HIS
COMPUTERS HE KNEW HOW TO GET
BODY PROTECTION, HE PLAYED A AN
ESPECIALLY BRUTAL GAME.
IT BREAKS UP MARRIAGES.
IF MY KID WAS MENTALLY
UNBALANCED I WAS WORKING
24-HOURS A DAY TO MAKE THEM
UNBALANCED I WOULD NOT TRAIN
THEM TO USE LETHAL WEAPONS.
>> WOULDN'T YOU HAVE LOCKED YOUR
GUNS UP?
>> ARE WE ASSUMING -- WE ARE
DOING THE EXACT THING AREN'T WE
JUMPING TO A CONCLUSION HE WAS
MENTALLY ILL.
CLEARLY HE HAD ISSUES.
WAS HE DIAGNOSED?
WAS HE ON MEDICATIONS?
>> I CAN'T REMEMBER IF IT WAS
WRITTEN BYRON IN THE NATIONAL
JOURNAL OR TWEETED BY HIM.
IT WAS ABOUT LET'S NOT JUMP TO
CONCLUSIONS HERE ABOUT A LINK I
THINK HE WAS SAYING IN THE
"WASHINGTON POST" THERE ISN'T
NECESSARILY A LINK BETWEEN
AUTISM AND VIOLENCE OR
ASPERGER'S AND VIOLENCE.
I THINK IT'S SMART TO TAKE A
STEP BACCALAUREATE THE
INVESTIGATORS DO THE POLICE WORK
THEY KNEED AND LET'S GET SOME
PSYCHIATRISTS, PEOPLE TOGETHER
TO SEE WHAT DO WE NEED TO DO TO
TRY TO HELP THESE FAMILIES
PREVENT TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS.
>> STARTED OFF WITH PROTECTING
THE SCHOOLS.
>> GOOD POINT.
>> YOU CAN DO THAT.
WHEN WE COME BACK THE POLITICS
OF GUNS.
IS IT TOO SOON?
MICHAEL BLOOMBERG IS MAKING A
BIG PUSH FOR GUN CONTROL.
SHOULD POLITICIANS BE PUSHING
THESE ISSUES SO QUICKLY?
THAT DISCUSSION WHEN WE COME
BACK.
NEW YORK
WITH MY COLLEAGUES.
>>> THIS IS THE FOURTH TIME WE
HAVE COME TOGETHER TO COMFORT A
GRIEVING COMMUNITY TORN APART BY
MASS SHOOTINGS.
WE CAN'T TOLERATE THIS ANY MORE.
THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
TO ENTHEM WE MUST CHANGE.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA CALLING FOR
CHANGE FOLLOWING THE SANDY HOOK
MASSACRE.
STOPPED SHORT OF DEFINING WHAT
THAT CHANGE SHOULD BE.
TODAY NEW YORK CITY MICHAEL
BLOOMBERG HAD NO PROBLEM
DEFINING THAT.
HE'S A GUN CONTROL ADVOCATE.
HE MADE HIS POSITION CLEAR
AGAIN.
>> TONIGHT THE PRESIDENT SAID HE
WOULD USE WHATEVER POWERS HIS
OFFICE HOLDS TO ADDRESS THIS
VIOLENCE.
I THINK IT IS CRITICAL THAT HE
DO SO.
CONGRESS AND THE WHITE HOUSE HAS
TO COME UP WITH SOMETHING THAT
STOPS THIS KARNAGE NO MATTER
WHAT THE POLITICAL RAMIFICATIONS
ARE.
>> SHOULD WE FOCUS ON GUN
CONTROL?
IS THE TIME RIGHT?
>> FRANKLY, I AM GETTING A
LITTLE BIT SADDENED BY PEOPLE
WHO SAY THAT THOSE OF US WHO
BELIEVE IN GUN CONTROL THAT NOW
IS NOT THE TIME TO TALK ABOUT
IT.
IT IS GENERALLY A WAY FOR GUN
ADVOCATES TO PUT OFF THE SUBJECT
UNTIL THINGS COOL DOWN.
NOW IS EXACTLY THE TIME TO TALK
ABOUT IT.
THERE IS NOW A QUESTION.
THAT IS SHOULD YOU HAVE A WILD
GUY EQUIVALENT OF AN M 16.
THAT IS AN ASSAULT WEAPON.
THE FIRST DAY OF THE NEW
CONGRESS A BAN ON ASSAULT
WEAPONS.
THERE WAS A BAN ON ASSAULT
WEAPONS FROM 94 TO 2004.
IT WAS NOT A REUP.
PRESIDENT BUSH STDECIDED NOT TO
REUP AND PRESIDENT OBAMA DECIDED
NOT TO REUP.
I UNDERSTAND THAT.
AT A MINIMUM, A BARE MINIMUM WE
HAVE TO TAKE ASSAULT WEAPONS AND
MAKE THEM ILLEGAL IN EVERY
POSSIBLE WAY.
THOSE GUNS DON'T HUNT ANIMALS
THEY HUNT PEOPLE.
>> THAT HAS TO BE ONE ELEMENT TO
LOOK AT GUNS BUT THAT'S NOT IT.
>> FIRST OF ALL AN ASSAULT
WEAPON.
FROM THE EARLY MORNING WE HAD A
MEETING I SAID I DON'T WANT TO
DO THIS GUN CONTROL DISCUSSION
RIGHT NOW THERE'S A DAY PLACE
AND A TIME FOR ALL THAT.
WE CAN'T DO IT.
LET'S NOT BE LIKE BLOOMBERG,
BILL MAHER BOB BECKEL AND JUMP
OUT WHILE WE ARE BURYING OUR
KIDS AS WE SPEAK.
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT GUNS.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
WE ARE USING DEATHS OF CHILDREN
TO PUSH OUR POLITICAL AGENDA.
YOU ARE MY GOOD FRIEND BUT YOU
ARE ABSOLUTELY WRONG.
>> YOU ARE WRONG TO SAY WE CAN'T
TALK ABOUT THIS NOW.
>> I REFUSE TO HAVE THIS
CONVERSATION.
>> WHEN WILL THAT TIME AND PLACE
BE?
>> WHEN OUR CHILDREN ARE BURIED,
BOB.
>> HOW ABOUT THIS.
BILL BENNETT FEELS DIFFERENT
LANED CONGRESSMAN GOER FEELS
DIFFERENTLY.
IF THAT PRINCIPAL HAD A GUN
INSTEAD OF LUNGING WITH JUST HER
BODY SHE WOULD BE ABLE TO TAKE
OUT THAT GUNMAN.
HERE'S WHAT BILL BENNETT
SUGGESTED EARLIER YESTERDAY.
>> I AM SURE I WILL GET MAIL FOR
THIS.
I AM NOT SO SURE I WOULDN'T WANT
ONE PERSON IN A SCHOOL ARMED,
READY FOR THIS KIND OF THING.
THE PRINCIPAL LUNGED AT THIS
GUY.
THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST LUNGED
AT THE GUY.
HAS TO BE SOMEONE WHO IS TRAINED
HAS TO BE SOMEONE RESPONSIBLE.
BUT MY GOD IF YOU CAN PREVENT
THIS KIND OF THING,IC Y I THINK
OUGHT TO.
>> SHOULD WE TALK ABOUT THIS
NOW?
>> WE ARE GOING TO TALK ABOUT
IT.
IT WAS INTERESTING I WAS
THINKING BACK, NOT ONE OF THE
OBAMA ROMNEY DEBATES THIS
QUESTION DIDN'T COME UP AT ALL.
THAT'S WHY I FEEL A LITTLE BIT
OH NOW YOU WANT TO TALK ABOUT
IT.
PRESIDENT OBAMA TALKED ABOUT --
HE MENTIONED FORT HOOD I
WOULDN'T PUT IT IN THE SAME
CATEGORY ON THAT ONE.
WHY COULDN'T BOTH THINGS BE
TRUE.
WHY DON'T WE TALK ABOUT ARMING
THE SCHOOLS AND THEN IF SOMEONE
CAN PROVIDE EVIDENCE THAT BAN ON
ASSAULT WEAPONS WOULD HELP
PREVENT THIS.
I WOULD BE OPEN MINDED UNLESS I
CAN THINK ABOUT THAT IN ADDITION
TO THE MENTAL HEALTH THINGS WE
HAVE BEEN TALKING ABOUT ON THIS
SHOW IN PARTICULAR FOR THE PAST
COUPLE OF MONTHS.
>> LOOK, THIS IS AN IMPORTANT
DISCUSSION.
I GO OUT TO THE FAMILY ON THIS
ON TERMS OF WHEN IS THE RIGHT
TIME TO DISCUSS THIS.
THE FUNERALS AND HONORING THE
LIVES OF THE VICTIMS IS
PARAMOUNT AND THEN HAVE
DISCUSSION WITH COURAGE AND
CLARITY BUT I BELIEVE WE NEED TO
HAVE IT.
>> LOOK AT GUNS LOOK AT
PROTECTING THE CLASSROOMS ALL
PART OF ONE COMMISSION GIVEN A
DEADLINE TO REDUCE THE ASSAULT.
>> I AM NOT SURE THE FAMILIES
WOULD WANT TO HAVE THE
DISCUSSION ABOUT GUN VIOLENCE.
SOMEONE GIVE ME ONCE TO HAVE AN
ASSAULT WEAPON IN THIS COUNTRY.
>> OKAY.
THERE'S A FANTASY LAND OF SAYING
WAE A MAGIC WAND IT WILL NEVER
HAPPEN AGAIN.
I THINK THE ARMY AND THE PEOPLE
IN THE SCHOOL TO MAKE SURE
THERE'S A DETERRENT.
THE COLORADO SHOOTER WENT TO
THREE MOVIE THEATERS BEFORE HE
WENT TO THAT ONE BECAUSE HE WAS
DETERRED, THERE WAS CONCEALED
CARRY WAS AVAILABLE AT THE OTHER
PLACE.
THAT WAS WHY.
THERE'S A DETERRENT FACTOR WHILE
WE TRANSITION INTO THE FANTASY
LAND OF THERE BEING NO GUNS.
>> I THINK IT WILL BE LOOKED AT.
IT WILL BE COMPREHENSIVE LOOK
AND HOPEFULLY NO POLITICS
INVOLVED IN IT.
15 MINUTES BEFORE THE TOP OF THE
HOUR.
WHEN SOMETHING LIKE THIS AWFUL
HAPPENS WHAT SHOULD SAY TO YOUR
KIDS, WHAT SHOULD YOU SAY TO
YOUR KIDS.
WILL YOU HEAR WHAT ONE PASTOR
TOLD THE BROTHER OF ONE OF THE
VICTIMS.
STAY WITH US.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS AMY. AMY LIKES
TO INVEST IN THE MARKET.
SHE ALSO LIKES TO RIDE
HER BIKE.
SHE KNOWS THE POTENTIAL
FOR MAKING OR LOSING MONEY
CAN POP UP ANYTIME.
THAT'S WHY SHE TRADES WITH
THE LEADER IN MOBILE TRADING.
SO SHE'S ALWAYS READY
TO TAKE ACTION,
NO MATTER HOW WILY...
OR WEIRD...
OR WONDERFULLY
THE MARKET'S BEHAVING...
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
>> ALMIGHTY AND EVER LASTING
GOD, AS WE GRIEVE THE LOSS OF
LIVE
LIFE IN THE NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT
SHOOTING SHOW US YOUR WAY AND
TEACH US YOUR PATH.
>> THAT WAS A PRAYER IN THE
SENATE AHEAD OF A MOMENT OF
SILENCE ON THE FLOOR FOR THE
VICTIMS OF THE FRIDAY SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
AS A PARENT HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN
SOMETHING SO EVIL FOR THE
CHILDREN WHO ASK WHAT HAPPENED.
HERE IS THE PASTOR AT LIMA
CATHOLIC CHURCH TOLD THE
BROTHERS OF ONE OF THE YOUNG
VICTIMS.
>> I STARTED TALKING WITH HIM.
HE SAID TO ME I DON'T HAVE
ANYBODY TO PLAY WITH ANY MORE.
I HAVE LOST MY BEST FRIEND.
I SAID TO HIM THAT GOD IS GOING
TO SEND YOU SOME WONDERFUL NEW
FRIENDS.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE AFRAID.
YOU WILL ALWAYS HAVE YOUR SISTER
IN YOUR HEART AND I SAID TO HIM
YOU DON'T HAVE TO WORRY BECAUSE
SHE IS VERY SAFE BECAUSE SHE IS
WITH GOD WE TALKED A LITTLE BIT
ABOUT WHAT HEAVEN WAS LIKE.
HE REALIZED THAT SHE WAS GOING
TO BE HAPPY, THAT SHE WAS GOING
TO BE SAFE, BUT IT WAS SHORTLY
AFTER THAT HE JUST BROKE DOWN
INTO TEARS.
>> I DON'T SUPPOSE MANY PEOPLE
FORTUNATELY HAVE HAD TO GO
THROUGH A TRAGEDY AS SEVERE AS
THIS.
WE HAVE ALL HAD OUR SHARE OF
TRAGEDIES IN OUR LIVES IN MY
CASE FROM A VERY DYSFUNCTIONAL
FAMILIES.
FOR YEARS I DIDN'T DEAL WITH IT
DIDN'T TALK TO ANYBODY ABOUT IT.
IT CAME BACK YEARS LATER TO
HAUNT ME IN MANY WAYS I WISH IT
HAD NOT INCLUDING CONTRIBUTING
TO ADDICTION.
ONE OF THE LESSONS IS YOU NEED
TO GET THIS OUT AS FAST AS YOU
CAN TALKING TO PEOPLE WHO KNOW
WHAT THEY ARE TALKING ABOUT.
OTHERWISE IT STAYS INSIDE
BURIED.
>> WE HAD THE PRINTS PAL OF
COLUMBINE.
RIGHT AWAY HE HAD PTSD.
HE KNOWS 10 YEARS FROM THE
SHOOTING TEACHERS BREAKDOWN TEN
YEARS LATER THEY WERE FINE BUT
THE MEMORIES AND SEEING KIDS
AGAIN IT BROUGHT IT ALL BACK.
>> FROM THE COLUMBINE TRAGEDY
THERE WAS NOT COMMISSIONS SO
MUCH BUT THERE WAS A LESSONS
LEARNED THING THAT THERE ARE
PEOPLE WHO CAN FAN OUT ACROSS
THE COUNTRY THAT CAN GO
IMMEDIATELY TO START HELPING THE
FAMILIES AND THE CHILDREN TO
START DEALING WITH WHAT WILL BE
A LIFELONG PROCESS.
>> I WAS GOING TO SAY QUICKLY I
WANT TO MAKE SURE WE GET
KIMBERLY IN HERE QUICKLY.
I HAD A DISCUSSION WITH MY SON
THREE OR FOUR TIMES HE PUSHED
BACK EVERY SINGLE TIME.
AROUND THE 4TH TIME HE STARTED
OPENING UP.
A TEENAGER HE IS 14.
A TEENAGER THEY HAVE EMOTIONS
THEY HAVE FEELINGS ABOUT IT THEY
NEED TO EXPRESS IT.
THEY PUSH BACK A LOT BECAUSE
THAT'S WHAT TEENS DO.
STAY ON THEM.
>> THIS IS SOMETHING I HAVE BEEN
TRYING TO SHIELD FROM HIM
BECAUSE I THINK IT'S TOO MUCH
FOR HIM AT HIS AGE TO FATHOM AND
UNDERSTAND.
I TRY TO KEEP THE HAPPY FOCUS
THEY ARE DOING GREAT THINGS
COUNSELING FOR THE OLDER KIDS
THAT ARE CONCERNED.
THEY HAVE ALSO INCREASED
SECURITY.
WHATEVER IT TAKES TO MAKE THE
KIDS FEEL THEY ARE IN A SAFER
PLACE.
UNFORTUNATELY BECAUSE OF TRAGEDY
WE BECOME ACOWS TOPPLED TO
HAVING SESSIONS AND THE
AFTERMATH BRINGING A TEAM IN TO
TRY TO PROVIDE PSYCHOLOGICAL
SERVICES FOR THESE KIDS.
AS YOU MENTIONED BRIAN THIS WILL
EXTEND ON FOR YEARS TO COME.
>> ONE MORE THING UP NEXT WE
WILL BE RIGHT BACK.
>> IT IS TIME NOW FOR ONE MORE
THING.
BOB YOU ARE GOING TO KICK US
OFF.
>> THE COUNTRY LOST A GREAT
PUBLIC SERVANT THE SENATOR OF
HAWAII 80 YEARS OLD HE DIED.
HE WAS A MEDAL OF HONOR WINNER
IN THE SECOND WORLD WAR.
HE SERVED WITH THE AMERICAN
INFANTRY GROUP.
ALL JAPANESE DISSENT.
HE WAS RUSHING A MACHINE GUN
LOST HIS ARM RECEIVED A MEDAL OF
ON ANOTHER.
INOUYE HE BECAME A NEW YORK
SENATOR AND HE WAS CHAIRMAN OF
THE INTELLIGENCE COMMITTEE.
HE WILL BE MISSED.
>> HE WAS AN INSTITUTION OF THE
SENATE.
>> HE WILL BE MISSED.
>> ERIC?
>> VERY QUICKLY WHEN WE GET BACK
TO RADIO NEWS I WOULD LOVE TO DO
THIS STORY.
WE NEED TO STAY ON THIS.
THIS IS A MARINE JOHN HAMMER.
LET'S TAKE A NEXT PICTURE.
THIS IS VERY IMPORTANT.
CHAINED TO A BED IN A MEXICAN
PRISON OVER A DISPUTE OVER A GUN
VIOLATION.
HE CROSSED THE BORDER WITH A GUN
THAT HAD REGISTRATION THAT WAS
IMPROPER.
HE IS STILL IN JAIL.
LOOK AT THAT.
CHAIN AROUND HIS ANKLE STRAPPED
TO HAD A BED.
GET THIS GUY OUT.
>> YOU THINK SOMEBODY IN
WASHINGTON COULD CALL SOMEONE IN
MEXICO.
>> OKAY.
ONE OF THE PICTURES THAT JUST
POPPED UP.
IT IS FROM OUR BEAR FRIEND GRETA
VAN SUSTEREN WHO WAS OVER THE
WEEKEND IN HAITI OVWITH HER
HUSBAND.
YOU ARE SEEING THE SHOTS OF
GRETA HOME AND ACADEMY F. YOU
LOOK AT THE TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT AND WHAT THEY ARE
DOING TO REVEREND GRETA VAN
SUSTEREN AND HER FAMILY TO
PROVIDE HOMES, TO PROVIDE
COMPUTERS, AN EDUCATION A CHANCE
AND A FUTURE FOR THESE CHILDREN
IN HAITI WHO SUFFERED ALREADY IN
THEIR SHORT LIFETIME.
THESE ARE SOME OF THE PHOTOS.
YOU CAN SEE MORE ON BERETTA
WIRE.COM.
>> GRETA AND JOHN ARE TWO OF THE
MOST GENEROUS PEOPLE IN AMERICA.
>> BILL HAMMER STARTED ON IT.
VICTOR CRUISE THE NEW YORK
GIANTS GOT NEWS.
JACK PINTO LOST HIS LIFE 6 YEARS
OLD TO THE HAIL OF GUN FIRE.
HE LOOKED UP TO VICTOR CRUZ HE
WROTE JACK PIN D