THIS.
SO MANY LIVES LOST, YOUNG
LIVES LOST.
AT THE SAME TIME, IT'S BEEN
TRULY INSPIRING TO SEE THE WAY
THE COMMUNITY HAS COME
TOGETHER TO SUPPORT ONE
ANOTHER.
>> GRETA: IT'S BEEN JUST
TERRIBLE.
I FRANKLY DON'T KNOW WHAT TO
SAY TO ANYONE HERE, BUT THANKS
FOR JOINING US.
>> YES.
MY PLEASURE.
>> GRETA: THANK YOU FOR BEING
WITH US TONIGHT.
STAY WITH US THROUGHOUT THE
WEEKEND BR FOR LATEST ON THE
SCHOOL MASSACRE HERE IN
CONNECTICUT G NIGHT FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
[ Male Announcer ]
WE ALL MAKE BAD DECISIONS.
LIKE SAY, GAS STATION SUSHI.
CHEAP IS GOOD.
AND SUSHI, GOOD.
BUT CHEAP SUSHI, NOT SO GOOD.
IT'S LIKE THAT SUPER-LOW RATE
ON NOT ENOUGH CAR INSURANCE.
PRETTY SKETCHY.
♪
AND THEN THERE ARE
THE GOOD DECISIONS.
LIKE ESURANCE.
THEIR COVERAGE COUNSELOR TOOL
HELPS YOU CHOOSE
THE RIGHT COVERAGE FOR YOU
AT A GREAT PRICE.
[ stomach growls ]
WITHOUT FEELING QUEASY.
THAT'S INSURANCE
FOR THE MODERN WORLD.
ESURANCE.
NOW BACKED BY ALLSTATE.
CLICK OR CALL.
>>> WE HAVE ENDURED TOO MANY
OF THESE TRAG DEC IN THE PAST
FEW YEARS AND EACH TIME I
LEARN THE NEWS, I REACT NOT AS
A PRESIDENT BUAS ANYBODY ELSE
WOULD, AS A PARENT.
AND THAT WAS ESPECIALLY TRUE
TODAY.
I KNOW THERE IS NOT A PARENT
IN AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL
THE SAME OVERWHELPING GRIEF
THEY DO.
THE MAJOR OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5-10 YEARS OLD .
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
ATHEM.
BIRTH DAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS, MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES TO HELPING
OUR CHILDREN FULFILL THEIR
DREAMS AND SO OUR HEARTS ARE
BROKEN TODAY.
MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF
THE VICTIMS AND IN THE WORDS
OF SPRITZER.
HEAL THE BROKENHEARTED AND
BIND UP THEIR WOUNDS.
>>> THAT WAS PRESIDENT OBAMA
EARLIER EMOTIONS RUNNING HIGH
AS THE COUNTRY COPES WITH THE
SENSELESS TRAG 20 CHILDREN AND
6 ADULTS AND BREAKING MOMENTS
AGO, A SOURCE TOLD THE AP MORE
THAN TWO GUNS WERE FOUND IN
THE SCHOOL.
IT WAS RECENTLY REPORTED THAT
TWO HANDGUNS WERE FOUND.
FEDERAL AUTHORITIES ARE
WORKING TO TRACE THOSE FIRE
ARMS.
JOINING ME TO HELP EXPLAIN
WHAT THE POLICE DO NOW AND
WHERE THEY GO IN THE
INVESTIGATION .
ROD WHEELER WAS TEACHING A
COURSE ON ACTIVE SHOOTERS.
AND FORMER NYPD DETECTIVE JOE
COFFEY.
HE SUPERVISED THE LATE SON OF
SAM INVESTIGATION IN THE
1970S.
OBVIOUSLY THIS KID HAS
EMOTIONAL PROBLEMS AND YOU
HAVE TO BE CRAZY AND/OR EVIL
TO KILL -- THESE ARE BABIES.
KINDERGARTENERS HERE.
YOU DEALT WITH THIS.
>>> THIS GUY IS A SOC PATH
LIKE ALMOST ALL OF THEM ARE.
PEOPLE SAY THEY ARE MENTALLY
ILL AND THEY PROBABLY ARE.
PEOPLE LIKE HIM, THEY ARE
SOCIO PATHS.
>>> MEANING THEY DON'T CENTER
A CONSCIENCE AND A SENSE OF
RIGHT AND WRONG AND NO GUILT
ASSOCIATED WITH BERKOWITZ.
SON OF SAM.
ED HIM MOTIVE.
MY MOTHER PUT MEAVE UP FOR
ADOPTION.
IT IS CRAZY.
>>> IT IS IT FALLING BACK ON
AN EXCUSE.
THEY ARE SOCIO PATHS.
>>> THEY ARE OFFERING
COUNSELING TO FIRST RESPONDERS
BECAUSE THE SCENE WAS SO
HORRIFIC AND THE FAMILIES, I
DON'T KNOW HOW AS A PARENT AND
I AM A PARENT OF TWO KIDS DO
YOU EVER OVERCOME I DON'T KNOW
HOW THE RECOVERY COMING IN.
BUWHAT ARE POLICE DOING.
THEY HAVE TO GO THROUGH THE
HORROR OF IDENTIFYING THE
BODIES AND GOING AND TELLING
THE PARENTS, WHERE DO THEY GO
FROM HERE?
>>> THEY HAVE TO RESPOND TO A
CALL THAT INVOLVES CHILDREN.
IT IS ONE OF THE WORST THAT A
POLICE OFFICER CAN GO TOMPT
WHEN YOU SEE THE THAT
THE OFFICERS SAW TODAY.
IT IS UNBELIEVABLE AND THEY
WILL HAVE CONFLICT AS A MATTER
OF FACT.
WH THE POLICE ARE DOING
RIGHT NOW, THERE IS A NUMBER
OF THINGS.
A NUMBER OF UNANSWERED
QUESTIONS THAT WE ARE TRYING
TO FIGURE OUT.
WHAT WAS THE MOTIVE BEHIND THE
GUYS ACTION.
GRANTED HE WAS A SOCIO PATH.
BUTHERE IS IT ALWAYS A SPARK
AND WARNING SIGNS IN EVERYONE
OF THESE CASES.
RIGHT NOW THE INVESTIGATORS
AND ATF.
THEY ARE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHERE THESE GUYS GOT THE
AMMUNITION FROM AND WEAPONS
FROM WHY DID HE SELECT THIS
SCHOOL AND CLASSROOM?
WE ARE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
ALL OF THAT NOW.
>>> YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE AN
INVESTIGATOR TO PEACE TOGETHER
THE FACT HIS MOTHER WORKED
THERE AND HE KILLED HIS MOTHER
AND WENT TO THE SCHOOL.
HE SUFFERED FROM PERSONALITY
DISORDER OR PERHAPS TUST --
AUTISTIC OR MEDICATION MAYBE.
WE'LL CHECK IN WITH MEDICAL
EXPERTS LATER.
>>> IN MY BUSINESS AND LAW
ENFORCEMENT AREA.
YOU CONFRONT EVIL.
HE WAS THE EPITOME OF EVIL AS
TIMOTHY MACVEIGH AND
BERKOWITZ.
THEY ARE CREATURES THAT
SHOULDN'T WALK THE EARTH.
AND THESE TYPE OF PEOPLE, THEY
ARE IMMUNE TO RIGHT AND WRONG.
THEY HAVE NO CLUE.
>>> ONE LAST QUESTION.
WHEN A COP WALKS IN AND SEES
THAT, COPS SEE A LOT IN THE
COURSE OF THEIR CAREER.
>>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>>> THIS HAS GOT TO BE
PARTICULARLY TRAUMATIC EVEN
FOR THEM.
THEY HAVE TO GO IN THERE AND
IDENTIFY AND PEOPLE HAVE TO
CLEAN THIS UP.
IT IS TO BE DIFFICULT FOR
EVERYBODY INVOLVED IN EVERY
LEVEL.
>>> IT IS IT THE WORST
SCENARIO THAT WE CAN FIND
OURSELVES N. ALL POLICE
OFFICERS ARE PROFESSIONALS AND
WE ARE TRAIN TOD RESPOND AND
WE HAVE TO RESPOND IN THESE
SITUATIONS.
BUWHEN IT INVOLVES CHILDREN IT
IS THE WORST THING YOU CAN
EVER EXPERIENCE.
WE STILL HAVE TO GO IN AND
REMEMBER THEM.
WHEN THE FIRST OFFICER GOT ON
THE SCENE, THEY HAD NO
ICALLYCLUE WHETHER THER HAD
KILLED HIMSELF.
THEY HAVE TO ATTEND TO THE
INJURED BUHAD AN ACTIVE
SHOOTER TO TAKE OUT.
IT IS A TERRIBLE SITUATION TO
DEAL WITH, SEAN.
>>> I KNOW ONE THING, THESE
POLICE OFFICERS, THEY WILL
LIVE WITH THIS FOR THE REST OF
THEIR LIVES.
>>> NO DOUBT.
I DON'T KNOW HOW THE PARENTS
RECOVER.
AS A PARENT I DON'T KNOW HOW
YOU RECOVER.
>>> COMING UP.
YOU ARE LOOKING AT HOBOKEN,
NEW JERSEY THE HOME. BROTHER
RYAN LANZA AND PLUS WORD IS
BREAKING ABOUT THE SHOOTER'S
MENTAL CONDITION.
WE HAVE THE DETAILS AND STAY
WITH US.
FOR THE CONTINUING DEVELOP AMS
AS THEY COME IN THE FOX NEWS
CHANNEL.
18 CHILDREN PRONOUNCED DEAD AT
THE SCHOOL AND TWO PRONOUNCED
DEAD AT THE HOSPITALS AND SIX
ADULTS PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE
SCHOOL.
THE SHOOTER IS DECEASED IN THE
>>> POLICE TRY TO PEACE
TOGETHER WHAT MADE 20 YEAR OLD
ADAM LANZA OPEN FIRE IN A
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL TODAY HIS
24 YEAR OLD BROTHER RYAN IS IN
POLICE CUSTODY BEING
QUESTIONED AT THIS HOUR.
THEY ARE OUTSIDE OF THE
APARTMENT IN HOBOKEN, NEW
JERSEY.
WHAT IS THE LATEST THAT YOU
ARE HEARING?
>>> JUST DURING THE COMMERCIAL
BREAK THEY WRAPPED UP THE
POLICE TAPE AND IT IS
GENERALLY A QUIET SCENE BEHIND
ME AND A VERY DIFFERENT SCENE
HERE AND PART OF THAT
CONFUSION LIKELY STEMMED FROM
THE FACT THAT RYAN LANZA ID
WAS FOUND ON ADAM LANZA.
YOU MENTIONED THAT HE IS
SPEAKING WITH POLICE.
THAT IS THE CASE.
HE IS NOT CONSIDERED A SUSPECT
NEITHER HE OR HIS GIRL FRIEND.
THEY ROLLED UP HERE EARLIER
THIS AFTERNOON AND A
RELIRADIABLE SOURCE SAID THEY
SAW POLICE SURROUNDING THE
BUILDING AND RYAN WAS HAND
CUFF TAKEN AWAY.
HE WAS DETERMINED NOT TO BE A
SUSPECT HOWEVER.
THERE WERE ALL THE SORTS OF
CONFLICTING REPORTS.
THEY THOUGHT SOMEONE WAS
MURDERED INSIDE OF THE
APARTMENT BUILDING BEHIND ME
OR THE FATHER.
THE FATHER IS COOPERATING WITH
THE FBI AND THEY ARE REALLY
TALKING TO THE FAMILY MEMBERS,
WE ARE LEARNING THAT ADAM
LANZA LIKELY HAD SOME FORM OF
AUTISM AND A PERMANENT
DISORDER.
BACK TO YOU.
>>> IS IT TRUE THAT RYAN HAD
NOT SPOKEN WITH ADAM IN TWO
YEARS,?
>>> WELL, SEAN I CAN TELL YOU
WE HEARD THE REPORTS, BUWE
HAVE NOT BEEN ABLE TO CONFIRM.
>>> THARCHING YOU.
AND IN THE AFTER MATH OF
TODAY'S TRAGEDY THERE WERE
REPORTS EARLIER THIS YEAR THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IMPLEMENTED SAFETY PROCEDURES
AND SO WHAT HAPPENED AND WHAT
ELSE CAN SCHOOLS DO TO PREVENT
INCIDENTS FROM HAPPENING IN
THE FUTURE?
JOINING ME IS DIRECTOR OF SAFE
HAVENS INTERNATIONAL.
I WAS PEEKING TO FRIENDS OF
MINE THAT ARE IN THE
EDUCATIONAL WORLD AND THEY ARE
VERY CLEAR, THIS SCHOOL WENT
ABOVE AND BEYOND TO GET BOO
SCHOOL, YOU HAD TO BE
IDENTIFIED, AND THEN BUZZED
IN.
AND IT SEEMS LIKE IN THIS
CASE.
THEY WERE DOING EVERYTHING
RIGHT, WHAT WOULD BE THE NEXT
STEP?
>>> SURE, THANKS FOR HAVING ME
ON.
AND WANT EXPRESS CONDOLENCES
TO THE COMMUNITY AND FAMILY.
I AM HEARING A NUMBER OF
INDICATIONS OF GOOD THINGS
THAT WERE IN PLACE IN THE
SCHOOL.
BUSECURITY IS ONLY STRONG AS
YOUR WEAKEST LINK.
YOU BUZZ THEM AND SCREEN THEM,
WE ARE COMMONLIED TO TEST
SECURITY AND CAN BREACH
SECURITY AND WE HAVE TO HAVE
GOOD TECHNOLOGY AND WE HAVE
EXCELLENT TECHNOLOGY TODAY AND
MAKE SURE WE ARE USING WHAT WE
KNOW ABOUT HOW PEOPLE CAN BE
TRAINED TO DETECT SUBTLE SIGNS
OF DANGER.
>>> DOES THAT MEAN.
>>> NO APPROACH IS FOOL PROOF.
>>> THAT'S THE POINT.
THE SON OF A TEACHER AT THE
SCHOOL WOULD BE SOMEBODY WHO
WOULD PROBABLY BE LET IN AND
YOU WOULDN'T KNOW AND THIS IS
IT A TOWN OF 27,000.
WELL-TO-DO COMMUNITY.
WALK IN AND GET FRISKED.
IS ANOTHER STEP THAT EVERY
COOL HAS ARMED GUARDS.
THEY CAN GET IN THERE FAIRLY
EARLY.
>>> THERE ARE OTHER TECH
TECHNIQUES THAT CAN BE USED .
WE HAVE HAD SHOOTINGS IN THE
SCHOOLS WITH METAL DETECTORS.
THERE ARE LIMITS TO THE
TECHNIQUES.
BUTHERE ARE THINGS IN TERMS OF
TRAINING OF STAFF AND PATTERN
MATCHING AND RECOGNITION AND
BASED AND STAFF IS TRAINED TO
PICK UP ON SUBTLE DIFFERENCES
WE SEE IT WHEN WE BUZZ IN THE
SCHOOLS TO TEST THEM.
I HAVE BEEN STOPPED BECAUSE
THEY DETECT SOMETHING IS NOT
RIGHT TO USE ABOUT THE STORE
TORE TO GET IN.
IF THE PERSON IS NORMALLY
COMING AND GOING FROM THE
SCHOOL IT WOULD BE UNREALISTIC
TO EXPECT THEY WOULD NOT BUZZ
THE SCHOOL INFORM WE'LL NOT
KNOW UNTIL THERE IS
INVESTIGATION .
A LOT OF SCHOOLS AND
ORGANIZATIONS PUT IN GOOD
TECHNOLOGY BUDON'T NECESSARILY
BACK TUP WITH GOOD TRAINING.
THE HUMAN BRAIN IS IT THE
GREATEST DEFENSE MECHANISM AND
STUR VIVAL MECHANISM KNOWN TO
MANKIND ACCORDING TO A
COLLEAGUE I RESPECT GREATLY.
HE'S RIGHT.
IF WE PROGRAM THE BRAIN AND
TEACH PEOPLE THERE ARE A
NUMBER OF INCIDENTS THAT HAVE
BEEN STOPPED THROUGH
TECHNIQUES.
BUNOTHING IS 100%.
>>> THANK YOU, SIR.
COMING UP NEXT.
WE ARE CONTINUING TO GET
DETAILS.
HIS BROTHER IS IN CUSTODY AND
PROVIDING CRUCIAL INFORMATION
ABOUT THE GUNMAN'S MENTAL
CONDITION.
WE'LL HAVE MORE ON THAT COMING
UP TODAY'S TRAGEDY REMINDS OF
COLUMBINE.
WE'LL SPEAK TO A FATHER WHO
LOST HIS DAUGHTER.
AND OFFERS THOUGHT TOTS
FAMILIES THAT LOST EVERYTHING
TODAY
THE SHOOTING APPEARS TO HAVE
STOPPED AND THE SCHOOL IS IN
LOCK DOWN.
>>> WE HEARD GUN SHOTS AND THE
GYM TEACHER DIRECTED US TO
STAY AGAINST THE WALL AND
EVERYONE STARTED PANICKING AND
THEN POLICEMEN CAME IN AND
THEY JUST LIKED IF HE WAS IN
HERE?
BUT THEN WE HAD TO CLIMB IN
THE CLOSEST.
WE HEARD MORE GUN SHOTS AND
THE AMBULANCE CAME AND THEN
THE POLICEMEN TOLD US TO RUN
OUT OF THE BUILD GO TO THE
FIRE DEPARTMENT.
>>> ONE LITTLE GIRL'S
FRIGHTENING ACCOUNT OF WHAT
HAPPENED IN SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AND THE COUNTRY MOURNS THE
TRAGEDY.
IT IS NOT THE FIRST SCHOOL
SHOOTING THAT THE NATION HAS
HAD TO DEAL WITH.
RACHEL WAS KILLED IN THE
COLUMBINE HIGH SCHOOL MASS
CURE.
DARRYL, AS A PARENT, ALL I CAN
THINK OF TODAY IS THESE
PARENTS OUT BUYING CHRISTMAS
GIFTS.
KIDS AT THIS AGE EXCITED ABOUT
SANTA CLAUS AND CHRISTMAS IS
IT COMING, AND NOW PLANNING A
FUNERAL AND NO CHRISTMAS OR
BIRTHDAYS, HOW DO YOU RECOVER?
YOU HAVE BEEN THROUGH THIS.
>>> WELL, THERE IS NOTHING YOU
CAN TELL A PARENT THAT LOST
THE CHILD.
THEY NEED THEIR FRIENDS AND
FAMILY.
IN OUR CASE, WE MADE CHOICES.
WE MADE THE CHOICE NOT TO BE
ANGRY AND BETTER BUT TO
CELEBRATE RACHEL'S LIFE AND
TODAY WE HAVE THE LARGEST
SCHOOL TRAINING PROGRAMS AND
REACH THREE MILLION STUDENTS A
YEAR WITH RACHEL'S CHALLENGE
AND TRAIN OVER 300,000
CHILDREN AND SCHOOL 500
SUICIDES PREVENTED.
A LOT OF THE ANSWERS ARE LONG
TERM.
THEY ARE NOT JUST A KNEE JERK
REACTION OR MORE LAWS AND
REGULATIONS .
BUT WE HAVE TO BE A KINDER
NATION AND TAKE TIME TO LISTEN
TO ONE ANOTHER AND BE ROLE
MODELS IN THESE KIDS.
AND YOU ARE ACTIVE AND IN YOUR
HEALING, AM I INTERPERTING IT
RIGHT.
MY SON CRAIG WAS IN THE
LIBRARY AND HE CAME WITHIN A
SPLIT SECOND OF BEING KILLED.
AND I WOULD HAVE LOST TWO
CHILDREN.
MY HEART GOES OUT TO THE
PARENTS WHO LOST THE CHILDREN
AND DEALING WITH THE TRAUMA OF
THE CHILDREN GOING THROUGH.
AND COUNSELING AND A THEY NEED
A LOT OF LOVE AND ATTENTION.
OUR HEARTS AND PRAYERS GO OUT
TO ALL OF THESE WONDERFUL POEM
THAT LOST CHILDREN TONIGHT.
>>> WHEN DUTHINK YOU STARTED
TO RECOVER.
IT TAKES A LONG TIME TO HEAL
THIS PAIN.
HOW LONG DID IT TAKE YOU TO
TURN THE CORNER A LITTLE BIT.
>>> HONESTLY, YOU NEVER
TOTALLY HEAL.
THERE IS ALWAYS A HOLE IN YOUR
HEART WHEN YOU LOSE A CHILD.
WE HAVE CHILDREN AND GRAND
CHILDREN.
BUT THERE IS ALWAYS A MISSING
GAP THERE WITH RACHEL.
IT DOES -- YOU GO THROUGH
STAGES OF SHOCK ASK DISBELIEF
AND ANGER AND WHOLE GAMUT OF
EMOTIONS AND THE INITIAL STING
IN THE FIRST TWO OR THREE
YEARS BEGINS TO WEAR OFF AND
YOU NEVER LOSE IT COMPLETEY
LOO.
AND CELEBRATING THEIR LIVES
AND FOCUS ON THAT AND NOT
DIRECT THE ANGER TOWARD THE
SHOOTER AND EVEN FRACTIS AND
THIS IS NOT A TIME FOR THOSE
PARENT TO HEAR BUT WE CHOSE TO
FORGIVE AND SOME PEOPLE CAN'T
DO THAT.
FORGIVENESS AND FOCUSING ON
THE POSITIVE IN YOUR CHILD'S
LIFE GOES A LONG WAY TO
HELPING.
DARRYL, SORRY ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED TO YOUR DAUGHTER AND
THANKS FOR SHARING YOUR
EXPERIENCE AND HELPING MORE
PEOPLE.
NAND THE SHOTTER MAY HAVE
SUFFERED FROM A PERSONALITY
DISORDER.
JOINING ME NOW ABOUT THE
SHOOTER'S MENTAL CONDITION.
WE HAVE DOCTORS HERE PART OF
THE FOX MEDICAL TEEM.
WE HEARD PERSONALITY DISORDER.
I HEARD THE TERM AUTISM AND
ASBERGER'S SYNDROME.
OBVIOUS LOW THE KID AT THIS
AGE SHOOTING HIS MOTHER AND
GOING INTO SHOOT WITH ABANDON
ALL OF THESE KIDS.
WOULD ANY OF THOSE CONDITIONS
TELL YOU THAT CAN HAPPEN?
>>> HE IS OUT OF TOUCH WITH
REALITY.
IF HE HAD ASBERGER'S HE MAY
HAVE HAD ONGOING MELT DOWNS
ASSOCIATED WITH VIOLENT
BEHAVIOR.
IT IS POSSIBLE HE WAS ON
MEDICATION AND IT WAS NOT
WORKING AND HE DIDN'T HAVE
EMPATHY AND HAD SOCIAL
PROBLEMS.
BUT THAT DOESN'T EXPLAIN
EVERYTHING AND GIVEN THE AGE
OF 20, THAT HE BECAME PSCOTIC
AND HE HAD A DELUSIONAL SYSTEM
THAT LED TO A HEINOUS CRIME.
>>> IS IT ALWAYS A MEDICAL
CONDITION.
IF SOMEONE IS DISCONNECTED
FROM ROLIT AND NO SIM THEE OR
CONSCIOUSNESS AND NO SOUL,
THERE IS HUMAN EVIL, I MEAN
SOMEBODY CAN KILL INNOCENT
CHILDREN LIKE IT SEEMS TO ME
THAT IS IT EVIL.
>>> I DON'T KNOW WHAT THE
DOCTOR'S OPINION IS ON I DON'T
LET POEM OFF OF THE HOOK AND
SAY IT IS IT A MENAL
CONDITION.
IT IS AN ISSUE OF EVIL HERE AS
WELL.
>>> HERE'S WHAT I THINK >>>
THE COMMON DENOMINATOR.
LACK OF EMPATHY.
YOU CAN'T WALK UP TO THE CHILD
AND KILL IT AND SIGH THE CHILD
FALL TO THE GROUND OR SLUMP
OVER AND MAINTAINING ANY
EMPATHY.
WHY CAN YOU LOSE HUMAN
YOU CAN BE DELUSIONAL AND
WORKING ON A DELUSIONAL
SYSTEM.
BUT YOU COULD BE IF YOU THINK
I DO THIS I SAVE THE WHOLE
WORLD.
AND THAT IS ONE LEVEL.
AND SURE PERSONALITY DISORDERS
CAN DO THIS AND OTHER
CONDITIONS LIKE DRUG ABUSE
COMBINED WITH EITHER A MOOD
DISORDER OR PERSONALITY OR ALL
THREE.
BUT IS IT A MENTAL ILLNESS.
OF COURSE IT IS.
THAT LACK OF EMPATHY DOESN'T
COME FROM NO WHERE.
AND IN 20 YEARS SEAN I NEVER
FOUND ANYBODY WHO DOES
ANYTHING LIKE THIS THAT BEEN
THROUGH HELL IN A WAY THAT
CREATES MENTAL ILLNESS.
>>> THIS IS IMPORTANT I THINK.
FIRST RESPHONDERS ARE GOING TO
NEED COUNSELING AND THE
PARENTS.
AS A PARENT THEY ARE GOING TO
NEED COUNSELING.
AND STUNES ARE GOING TO BE
TRAUMATIZED AND POST TRAUMATIC
STRESS AND DIFFERENT AND ALL
LIKE WANT TROOPS GO THROUGH.
WHAT DO YOU EXPECT TO HAPPEN
TO THE PEOPLE IN >>> THE VET
ADMINISTRATION LOCKED AT 600
KIDS WHO WERE, THANK GOD
WEREN'T KILLED WILL HAVE
STRESS DISORDER AND THEY WILL
BE AGGRESSIVE, SAD OR NOT
FEELING HELP AND NOT SLEEPING
WELL.
IT CAN LAST FOR MONTHS AND
MONTHS IF NOT YEARS.
COGNITIVE THERAPY HELPS.
THANK YOU.
AND COMING UP NEXT.
A FORMER RESIDENT OF THAT
TIGHT KNIT COMMUNITY IS
STANDING BY.
THAT IS COMING UP NEXT RIGHT
HERE ON HANNITY.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO HANUTY AS
WE CONTINUED THE REPORT ON THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
WE GO BACK TO CONNECTICUT
WHERE A RESIDENT OF THAT TIGHT
KNIT COMMUNITY IS JOINING US.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US.
>>> YOU'RE WELCOME, SEAN.
>>> TELL US ABOUT THE PRAYER
VIGIL AND INFORMATION YOU
MIGHT HAVE PICKED UP TODAY.
>>> THE PRAYER VIGIL WAS
ABSOLUTE LOW BEAUTIFUL.
IT WAS JUST UNBELIEVABLE HOW
MANY PEOPLE SHOWED UP AT THIS
CHURCH AND PEOPLE OUTSIDE AND
JUST CRYING.
AND LOVE AND HUGGING EACH
OTHER.
IT WAS ABSOLUTELY WONDERFUL.
>>> YEAH.
>>> I AM STOW GLAD I ATTENDED
IT.
>>> I AM GLAD YOU DID AS WELL.
I KNOW THE COMMUNITY WILL NODE
A LOT OF HEALING.
IT IS IT A VERY SMALL
TIGHT-KNIT TOWN.
27,000 PEOPLE AND KNOWN AS A
SAFE NEIGHBORHOOD, CORRECT?
>>> ABSOLUTELY.
THERE IS NO CRIME IN NEWTOWN.
THIS IS IT JUST AN ISOLATED
INCIDENT AND HE WAS NOT EVEN A
RESIDENT HERE.
HE WAS FROM NEW JERSEY AND HE
USED TO LIVE THERE.
>>> HIS MOTHER LIVED NEARBY
AND SHE WAS KILLED BEFORE HE
WENT ON THE SCHOOL RAMPAGE.
>>> UNBELIEVABLE.
IT IS VERY, VERY SAD.
>>> WERE THERE PARENTS AND
SOME OF THE KIDS FROM THE
SCHOOL AT THE VIGIL, MA'AM?
NYES, YES, CRYING.
JUST HUGGING THEIR PARENTS AND
CRYING.
AND I WAS HUGGING MY GRAND
DAUGHTER AND MY DAUGHTER, IT
WAS JUST THARCHINGFUL THAT WE
ARE ALIVE.
>>> THANK YOU, FOR SHARE THAG
WITH US.
WHEN WE COME BACK OUR GOOD
FRIEND BO DEDLE IS WITH US.
AND YOU WILL HEAR WHAT ONE
FIRST GRADE TEACHER TOLD HER
STUDENTS WHEN THEY WERE
WAITING FOR THE POLICE TO
ARRIVE.
THAT EMOTIONAL STORY IS COMING
UP NEXT.
(SIREN)
SNOTE
>> I AM THINKING AS A SIX OR
SEN YEAR OLD WHAT ARE YOUR
THOUGHTS?
I AM THINKING I HAVE TO BE
THEIR PARENT AND HAVE TO TELL
THEM AND I SAID I NEED YOU TO
KNOW THEY LOVE YOU ALL VERY
MUCH.
AND THAT IT IS GOING TO BE
OKAY.
I THOUGHT THAT WAS THE LAST
THING WE WERE GOING TO HEAR
AND I THOUGHT WE WERE ALL
GOING TO DIE .
I DON'T KNOW IF THAT IS OKAY,
TEACHERS, BUT I WANTED THEM TO
KNOW I LOVED THEM AND THAT
WOULD BE ONE OF THE LAST
THINGS THEY HEARD AND NOT THE
GUN FIRE IN THE HALLWAY.
IT IS HORRIBLE, HORRIBLE.
>> THAT WAS A FIRST GRADE
TEACHER IN SANY HOOK
ELEMENTARY THINKING ABOUT HER
UNBELIEVABLE DAY AND LIKELY TO
HEAR MORE STORIES AS THE
TRAGEDY UNFOLDS .
HERE IS DR. MICHAEL BODEN.
FORMER NYPD DETECTIVE BO.
AND PSYCHE THERAPIST IS HERE
WITH US.
TUNES AND TEACHERS AND BO HAS
SEWN A LOT IN HIS DAY.
THEY WILL BE DEALING WITH A
LOT.
>> IT IS EXTRAORDINARILY
NTO THE PARTNERS THE MOST?
>> RIGHT.
GETTING HEALING IS MOST
IMPORTANT.
WHAT PARENTS CAN DO FOR THE
CHILDREN.
GET THEM HOME SO THEY ARE IN A
COMFORTABLE SITUATION AND
PROVIDE THEM WITH STRUCTURE.
STRUCTURE IS VERY COMFORTING
AND NOT OVERWHELM THEM WITH
TOO MUCH INFORMATION BUT BE A
PERSON .
>> WOULD YOU HAVE THEM GO TO
VIGILS AND FUNERALS OR DEPENDS
ON THE KID.
>> IT DEPENDS ON THE KID AND
THE SITUATION.
IF THEIR CHILD LOST A GOOD
FRIEND IT MIGHT BE GOOD TO
TAKE THEM TO THE FUNERAL.
IT WOULD BE OKAY.
AND THEY DON'T GET FRIGHTENED
AND IT IS OKAY TO HAVE A
BROADRANGE OF E.
- EMOTION .
>> I HAVE SIX CHILDREN AND
1984, WE HAD THE PALM SUNDAY
MASSCURE.
THIS MAN WENT IN A HOUSE AND
SHOT AND KILLED 10 KIDS.
THEY WERE ALL SITTING AROUND
AND NO ONE RAN AWAY.
IT IS IT A FREEZE THING.
WHEN SOMEONE IS SYSTEMATICALLY
SHOOTING PEOPLE KIDS FREEZE.
IT IS LIKE THEY WERE ALL 12
AND UNDER.
SIX YORE OLD AND FIVE YORE OLD
AND THESE KIDS WERE ALL
SITTING AROUND AND ALL HAD
SHOTS.
>> YOU SAW TEMPERATURE >>
VIVID IN MY MIND AND THE FIRST
RESPONDERS I AM SURE THAT WAS
HORRIFIC.
10 DAY I SAW AND LARGEST MASS
MURDER IN NEW YORK HISTORY
BEFORE 9/11.
THAT IS BURNED IN MY BRAIN.
I CAN JUST IMAGINE WHAT THIS
WAS.
HOW COME THERE WAS NO
SURVIVORS.
THIS PUNK.
PROBABLY SHOT THEM IN THE HEAD
AND IF HE SHOT BODY SHOTS, WE
WOULD HAVE HAD A LOT MORE
SURVIVORS.
>> DOCTOR, YOU HAVE SEEN MANY.
NI DID THE AUTOPSIES ON THOSE.
>> YOU HAVE SEEN A LOT.
HOW DO YOU KIND OF, I GUESS IT
IS LIKE ANY JOB, YOU HAVE TO
FIND A WAY TO COMPARTMENTALIZE
WHAT YOU ARE WITNESSING OR YOU
DON'T SURVIVE.
>> IN A SENSE, THE DECEEDENTS
ARE OUT OF THE PAIN AND
MISERY.
IT IS IT THE PARTNERS AND
FAMILIES.
THEY ARE GOING THROUGH A STATE
THAT WILL LAST A FEW DAYS
UNTIL THEY GET THEIR BABIES
BACK.
THE SIVENADULTS WILL BE
AUTOPSIED ESPECIALLY THE
PERPETRATOR.
BUT THE CHILDREN HAVE TO BE
EXAMINED AND THEY HAVE
DOCUMENT THE INJURIES ON THE
CHILDREN AND IF THERE ARE
BULLETS IN THE BODIES THEY
HAVE TO BE REMOVED.
TO MATCH IT UP TO THE WEAPONS
AND MAKE SURE THERE WAS NOT A
WEAPON THEY DON'T KNOW ABOUT.
IT TAKES TIME.
>> IT COMES BACK.
AND I HAVE BEEN INVOLVED WITH
THIS SAFE SCHOOL THING AND SEE
SOMETHING NOTIFY.
AND CALL NUMBER THERE.
AND IT IS COMING DOWN.
I GET CALLS IN THE OFFICE.
SCHOOLS NOW ARING FOR OFF DUTY
COPS WITH A GUN.
LET'S BE HONEST IF A GUY HAD A
GUN, HE MIGHT HAVE KILLED SOME
PEOPLE YOU WOULD AT LEAST BE
ABLE TO LIMIT IT.
>> THAT'S WHAT I WANT.
>> THAT'S WHY THEY TARGET
SCHOOL SYSTEMS.
>> IT IS GOING TO COME DOWN TO
IT.
THESE ARE PRECIOUS THINGINGS.
WE'LL PAY FOR A RETIRED COP
WITH A GUN SO ONE OF THESE
PUNKS COME IN.
HE WILL NOT HAVE FREE WILL.
IF HE HAD MORE BULLETS AND
TIME, HE COULD HAVE KILLED
MORE UNTIL THOSE COPS GOT
THERE.
IT IS HORRIFIC.
>> I THINK WE ARE HEADED THERE
ESPECIALLY COPS IN NEW YORK.
>> I THINK IT IS IT GREAT.
BUT THE GOOD NEWS, KIDS ARE
RE