VENICE CALIFORNIA .
THIS IS CHIP SITTING ON
SANTA'S LAP.
>> THIS IS FROM ARNIE.
HE IS LITTLE ONE WITH TWO
BROTHERINGS BACK IN 1954 .
>> AND THIS IS HARRISON.
BACK IN 1965.
THEY DON'T LOOK TOO HAPPY.
>> I LOVE THE TINCELL ON THE
TREE.
YOU CAN TWEET THEM TO US .
SEND IT TO FOX NEWS.COM.
>> HAVE A GREAT DAY, WE'LL SEE
YOU LATER.
"FOX AND FRIENDS" STARTS RIGHT
NOW.
BYE.
>> >> Gretchen: GOOD MORNING,
EVERYONE.
I AM GRETCHEN CARLSON.
THANKS FOR SHARING YOUR SUSAN
RICE WANTS OUT.
SHE ASKED NOT TO BE CONSIDERED
FOR SECRETARY OF STATE.
THAT WILL PUSH HER INVOLVEMENT
IN LIBYA RIGHT UNDER THE RUG.
>> Steve: PARENTS PLEADING FOR
HELP.
THE UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT
IS JOINING THE FIGHT.
CAN THEY FRO OUR MARINE FROM
MOKESCO.
THAT'S STRAIGHT AHEAD ?
>> Brian: A HIGH SCHOOL
BASKETBALL TEAM LOSE BY 105
POIGNS .
OTHER THAN THE PARENTS WANT TO
KNOW WHY THAT WAS ALLOWED TO
HAPPEN.
TOUGH LOVE OR BASKETBALL BEAT
DOWN.
THEY DEFINITELY LOST.
"FOX AND FRIENDS" STARTS RIGHT
NOW.
>> I WANT TO WISH EVERYBODY
HAPPY HANUKKAH AND HAPPY
CHRISTMAS AND GO GIANTS.
MR. #1: YEAH, THERE IS SCOTTY.
>> Brian: WHY ARE YOU TAKING
SIDES, SCOTT ?
YOU JUST WANT ALL TIMES TO
PLAY WELL, RIGHT.
>> Gretchen: NO, HE DOESN'T.
HE IS NOT A FAIR WEATHER FAN.
I LIKE THAT.
HE HAS CONVICTION AND SAYS
WHAT HE THINKS.
>> Brian: THOSE SUPERBOWL
CHAMPIONSHIPS, YOU ARE
WALKING.
>> Gretchen: SCOTT HAPPENS TO
BE A FANTASTIC SINGER AND
DANCER.
>> Steve: HE IS.
>> Brian: THAT SCOTT.
>> Gretchen: THAT SCOTT, RIGHT
THERE .
I AM GLAD HE'S ON MY CAMERA.
>> Brian: HAVE YOU ACTUALLY
SEEN EVIDENCE .
♪ BEFORE --
>> Gretchen: I TOLD YOU.
YOU GOT TO KNOW YOUR CAMERA
GUYS.
>> Brian: WE KNOW THEM.
>> Steve: THAT WAS SCOTT.
>> Gretchen: IAN PUT HIM OUT
OF FOCUS AGAIN.
>> Brian: IAN.
FOR A CHANGE PUT ME IN FOCUS.
>> Gretchen: OUR CHRISTMAS
PARTY IS COMING UP AND WE'LL
ALL BE OUT OF FOCUS.
>> Brian: IAN ACCORDING TO
REPORTS WILL NOT BE GOING.
>> Gretchen: WHY ?
>> IT IS HANUKKAH.
>> Steve: HE HAS A CONFLICT.
WE'LL START ABOUT THIS.
ARE WE SPEAKING OF FOCUS IT IS
BECOMING CLEARER, SUSAB RICE
WILL NOT BE OUR NEXT SECRETARY
OF STATE.
>> Brian: I WOULD LIKE TO WITH
DRAW MINE AS WELL.
>> Steve: SHE SAID ESSENTIALLY
THE ADMINISTRATION CAN'T
AFFORD A FIGHT OVER BENGHAZI.
THE BIG QUESTION IS, DID SHE
FALL ON HER SWORD OR DID THE
WHITE HOUSE HAND HER ONE.
CLEARLY SHE WAS THROWN UNDER
THE BUS.
>> Gretchen: THIS IS WHAT SHE
WROTE ON SEPTEMBER 16TH WHEN
SECRETARY OF STATE WAS
UNAVAILABLE AFTER A GRUELING
WEEK, THE WHITE HOUSE ASKED ME
TO APPEAR ON FIVE SUNDAY TALK
SHOWS.
I RELIED ON FULLY CLEARED
UNCLASSIFIED POINTS PROVIDED
BY THE INTELLIGENCE COMMITTEE.
THE UNCLASSIFIED POINTS WERE
CONSISTENT WITH THE CLASSIFIED
ASSESSMENTS, I RECEIVED.
FIRST OF ALL WAS HILLARY
CLINTON REALLY NOT AVAILABLE
OR DID SHE SAY SHE DIDN'T WANT
TO GO TELL SOMETHING THAT WAS
NOT THE TRUTH.
AS KATHERINE HERITAGE, UN
AMBASSADOR RICE HAD ACCESS TO
THE PDP.
PRESIDENTIAL DAILY BRIEFING
BEFORE SHE WENT OUT ON THE
TALK SHOW AND TALKED ABOUT THE
FACT THAT IT WAS PROBABLY A
TERRORIST ATTACK.
>> Brian: CHARLES KRAUTHAMMER
SAID NOW THAT RICE IS OUT AND
THE PRESIDENT DECIDED NOT TO
FIGHT THE FIGHT HERE.
IT MINES THE END OF PURSUING
THE TRUTH WITH THE BENGHAZI
ATTACK.
>> CLEARLY HAD SHE BEEN
NOMINATED THE BENGHAZI SCANDAL
WOULD BE ON THE FRONT PAGE.
I THINK IT WILL DIE NOW IN THE
MAIN STREAM MEDIA.
THEY HAVE NO INTEREST IN THE
STORY.
I THINK HE WOULD RATHER HAVE
HAD HER AND HE HAD YIELDED .
HER CONSOLATION WILL BE HE
WILL MAKE HER NATIONAL ADVISOR
AND THAT DOES NOT REQUIRE THE
ASSET -- ASCENT OF THE SENATE.
>> Steve: WHEN YOU LOOK AT HER
RECORD ON SYRIA AND AFRICA, IT
WAS NOT GOOD.
MAUREEN DOWD SAID RICE IS TOO
AUTOMATICBITIOUS AND
UNPRINCIPLED.
DANA MILBANK SAID HER ATTITUDE
WAS A PROBLEM .
HILLARY CLINTON BEGIN THE
CHOICE BETWEEN JOHN KERRY AND
SUSAN RICE.
SAID I WOULD RATHER HAVE JOHN
KERRY.
HE CAN TALK FOR HOURS AND NOT
SAY ANYTHING AND SPEAKS
FRENCH.
>> Gretchen: I WAS DOING
STUDIO B .
AND HE WAS PROBABLY UNCORKING
THE CHAMPAGNE.
THERE IS SUPPOSEDLY A REPORT
ON BENGHAZI COMING OUT.
USUALLY THEY MAKE THE
ANNOUNCEMENTS ON FRIDAY.
COULD IT BE THE REPORT IS
COMING OUT TODAY AS THE FRIDAY
RELEASE OR SOMETIME SOON?
WILL THAT MEAN HILLARY CLINTON
WILL NOT TESTIFY ON DECEMBER
20TH IF SHE WANTS TO RUN FOR
PRESIDENT, AND MODERATE
REPUBLICAN SUSAN COLLINS, THE
SENATOR, MAYBE SHE WAS THE
FINAL NAIL IN THE COFFIN.
WHEN SHE CAME OUT AND SAID SHE
STILL HAD QUESTIONS.
IF MODERATE REPUBLICANS WOULD
NOT SAY YES, IT WAS OVER.
>> Brian: I DON'T AGREE WITH
CHARLES KRAUTHAMMER.
I - A LOT OF NAVE I SEALS AND
MILITARY PEOPLE WANT TO KNOW
WHY THEY WERE SACRIFICED.
AN DREA MITCHELL HAS A
STAGGERING REVIEW WHAT THIS
MEANS FOR REPUBLICANS THAT
AMBASSADOR RICE WAS NOT
NOMINATED.
>> I THINK IT WAS AN
IMPOSSIBLE CHALLENGE FOR HER
TO BE CONFIRMED AND THE WHITE
HOUSE KNEW THAT.
THEY KNOW THEY ARE ON GOOD
POLITICAL SOLID GROUND AND
THIS WILL NOT HELP REPUBLICANS
AT ALL THE FACT THAT A WOMAN
OF COLOR WAS FORCED OUT OF THE
CONFIRMATION PROCESS BEFORE
SHE WAS NOMINATED.
>> Gretchen: HER RACE HAS
NOTHING TO DO WITH IT OR HER
GENDER.
WE HAVE HAD MADELYNE ALBRIGHT
AND CONDOLEEZZA RICE WHO FITS
BOTH OF THE CRITERIA.
>> Steve: NOMINATED BY THE
REPUBLICAN.
>> Gretchen: WE HAVE HAD
HILLARY CLINTON.
WHO WAS THE LAST MALE
SECRETARY OF STATE ?
>> Brian: COLIN POWELL .
FOR EVERYBODY TO SEE RACE AND
GENDER IN THIS IS INCREDIBLE.
THAT HAS NOTHING TO DO WITH IT
AND THAT THE FACT PEOPLE ARE
LOOKING FOR THAT AS A
POLITICAL PLUS OR MINUS.
WHERE ARE WE AT WITH RACE
RELATIONS IN THIS COUNTRY ?
IT SEEMS LIKE WE ARE BACK IN
1960.
>> Steve: IT COULD BE GOOD
NEWS FOR HOWARD SCHOOL BROWN
WHO WAS BEATEN IN THE ELECTION
.
IF THERE IS A SPECIAL ELECTION
TO REPLACE JOHN KERRY IF HE
BECOMES SECRETARY OF STATE,
SCOTT BROWN WOULD BE A SHOE
IN.
>> Brian: HE HIT THE GROUND
RUNNING.
>> Steve: AND ONE OTHER
WRINKLE FOR SCOTT BROWN.
UVAL PATRICK IS NOT GOING TO
RUN FOR REELECTION .
IF NOT SENATE MAYBE GOVERNOR.
>> Gretchen: I THOUGHT HE WAS
GOING TO DO MORE SPREADS FOR
GQ.
>> Steve: HE DID A NAKED SHOT.
>> Brian: JUST TO MAKE END'S
MEET.
>> Gretchen: WHEN HE WAS YOUNG
AND HE WAS AN ATTRACTIVE >>
Brian: WE HAVE ALL DONE NAKED
PHOTOGRAPHS AT ONE POIGN.
>> Gretchen: NO, NO, NO.
I HAVE NOT.
WE'LL SET THE RECORD STRAIGHT
NOW, I HAVE NOT.
IF HE IS NOT ANSWERING THE
QUESTION.
>> Steve: I DON'T REMEMBER
MONEY EXCHANGING HANDS WITH
THAT PICTURE.
>> Gretchen: THIS IS FOR THE
AFTER THE SHOW, SHOW.
>> Brian: LONG WAY TO GO
BEFORE THAT.
>> Gretchen: MAYBE FOR THE
CHRISTMAS PARTY.
FOX NEWS ALERT, THE UNITED
STATES RAMPING UP ITS
INVOLVEMENT IN THE CRISIS IN
SYRIA.
LEON PANETA SIGNING OFF ON
SENDING TWO PATRIOT MISSILES
AND TROOPS TO TURKEY TO BEEF
UP THE COUNTRY'S DEFENSE UNDER
SYRIA ATTACK.
THE MISSILES WILL BE UNDER
NATO CONTROL.
WASHINGTON SETS UP THE
INSURANCE EXCHANGINGS UNDER
OBAMA CARE.
SO FAR 23 STATES OPTED OUT
MEANING THAT THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT WILL HAVE TO RUN IT
FOR THEM.
19 WILL HAVE STATE RUN
EXCHANGES AND SIX PLAN ON
PARTNERING WITH THE FIDS AND
VIRGINIA AND FLORIDA ARE THE
ONLY TWO STATES THAT HAVE NOT
MADE A DECISION.
WE ARE 18 DAYS FROM GOING OVER
THE FISCAL CLIFF AND PRESIDENT
AND JOHN BOEHNER HARD AT WORK
TO AVIRT A DISASTER.
THEY MET AT THE WHITE HOUSE
FOR 50 MINUTES.
NEITHER SIDE WOULD GO IN
DETAILS, BUT THE MIGHTING CAME
HOURS AFTER SPEAKER BOEHNER
CRITIZED THE PRESIDENT FOR AN
UNWILLINGNESS TO COMPROMISE.
>> THE PRESIDENT PROMISED THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE A BALANCED
APPROACH, HIS PROPOSALS ARE
ANYTHING BUT.
HE WANTS FAR MORE IN TAX HIKES
THAN SPENDING CUTS.
BOEHNER SAID TALKS WERE DOING
GREAT.
DO YOU FEEL THE NEED FOR SPEED
?
THAT IS FOREVERMORE WWE
WRESTLER.
U.S. NAVY LET HIM TAKE A RIDE
IN THE FIGHTER JET FOR THE
ANNUAL TRIBUTE FOR THE TROOPS.
HOW FAST DID HE G. HE WENT 900
MILES PER HOUR.
DON'T WORRY.
THEY MADE HIM GO THROUGH
TRAINING.
I WONDER IF HE HAD THE BARF
BAD.
>> Brian: IT IS IMPOSSIBLE TO
GO THROUGH AND NOT THROW UP ?
>> Steve: IT HAPPENS A LOMPT
-- LOT.
>> Brian: IF YOU HAD TAKEN A
FLIGHT THAT FAST.
>> Steve: IN A AIRPLANE.
11 MINUTES AFTER THE HOUR.
HE FACED DOWN IRAQI INSURGENTS
BUT THE TREATMENT IN PRISONS
HAD THE FAMILY TERRIFIED.
>> Gretchen: NO CHRISTMAS
CONCERT, KIDS.
HOW ABOUT AN ANTI-BULLYING
SPEECH, INSTEAD THAT STORY.
I DON'T KNOW.
♪
YEARS AGO, MY DOCTOR TOLD ME
TO TAKE A CENTRUM SILVER
MULTIVITAMIN EVERY DAY.
I TOLD HIM, SURE.
CAN'T HURT, RIGHT?
THEN I HEARD THIS NEWS
ABOUT A MULTIVITAMIN STUDY
LOOKING AT LONG-TERM
HEALTH BENEFITS FOR MEN OVER 50.
THE ONE THEY USED
IN THAT STUDY...
CENTRUM SILVER.
THAT'S WHAT I TAKE.
MY DOCTOR!
HE KNOWS HIS STUFF.
[ Male Announcer ] CENTRUM.
THE MOST RECOMMENDED.
MOST PREFERRED.
MOST STUDIED.
CENTRUM,
ALWAYS YOUR MOST COMPLETE.
Neural speeds
increasing to 4G LTE.
Brain upgrading to a quad-core
processor.
Predictive intelligence
with Google Now complete.
Introducing DROID DNA by HTC.
It's not an upgrade
to your phone.
It's an upgrade to yourself.
A Hybrid? Most are
just no fun to drive.
Now, here's one that will
make you feel alive.
Meet the five-passenger
Ford C-MAX Hybrid.
C-MAX says ha.
C-MAX says wheeee.
Which is what you get,
don't you see?
Cause C-MAX has lots more
horsepower than Prius v,
a hybrid that C-MAX
also bests in MPG.
Say hi to the all-new 47
combined MPG C-MAX Hybrid.
AND WITH MY BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CREDIT CARD,
I LOVE 'EM EVEN MORE.
I EARN 1% CASH BACK EVERYWHERE,
EVERTIME.
2% ON GROCERIES.
3% ON GAS.
AUTOMATICALLY.
NO HOOPS TO JUMP THROUGH.
THAT'S 1% BACK ON...
[ toy robot sounds ]
2% ON PUMPN PIE.
AND APPLE.
3% BACK ON 4 TRIPS
TO THE AIRPORT.
IT'S AS EASY AS..
-[ man ] 1...
-[ woman ] 2...
[ woman ] 3.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CARD.
APPLY ONLINE OR AT
A BANK OF AMERICA NEAR YOU.
>> Gretchen: 15 MINUTES AFTER
THE HOUR.
HE SURVIVED IRAQ AND
AFGHANISTAN WARS ONLY TO FINE
HIMSELF JAIL WOULD IN A
MEXICAN PRISON.
HE DECIDED TO TAKE A VACATION
AND HE WAS JAILED FOR
POSSESSING A REGISTERED
WEAPON.
HE WAS TARGETS OF THREAT AND
EXTORTION BY CARTEL MEMBERS
LOOKING TO MAKE A PROFIT.
DESPITE THE DIFFICULT ORDEAL
HE IS SHOWING INCREDIBLE
STRENGTH.
>> WE GAVE HIM A PHONE NUMBER
OF SOMEONE TO CALL.
IF SOMETHING HAPPENS AND WE
CAN'T GET THERE AND TAKE HOURS
TO GET THERE, WE HAD MADE
ARRANGEMENTS FOR MACHINE TO
PICK TUP.
HE WROTE IT IN MY BIBLE.
THEY MAY NOT LET YOU TAKE
ANYTHING OUT .
HE
THEY ARE NOT TAKING MY BIBLE.
HE'S HANGING AND HE'S TOUGH.
>> Gretchen: AND NOW A
CONGRESSWOMAN STEPPED IN TO
HELP THE FAMILY BRING JOHN
HOME.
CONGRESSWOMAN THANK YOU FOR
GETTING UP EARLY.
I KNOW YOU ARE WORKING WITH
THE FAMILY AND I INTERVIEWED
HIS MOTHER THE OTHER DAY .
HER FIRST BREW NATIONALLY AND
SHE WAS SCARED AND CAME TO YOU
FOR HELP.
WHAT CAN YOU DO ?
>> IT IS IT A TRICKY SITUATION
FOR THE FAMILY.
AS YOU POINTED OUT.
HE'S BEEN INCARCERATED SINCE
AUGUST FOR A TECHNICAL NOTHING
CRIME.
HE TRIED TO DO THE RIGHT
THING.
HE ASKED OUR U.S. CUSTOM AND
BORDER AGENTS, CAN I BRING THE
FIREARM IN TO MEXICO.
THEY PHOTOGRAPHED IT AND
MEASURED IT AND WEIGHED IT AND
SAID FILL OUT THE FORMS AND HE
WAS IN THE MEXICAN AUTHORITY
OFFICE WHEN HE WAS JAILED WHEN
HE WAS TRYING TO REG I FELTER
HIS WOMAN.
THE FAMILY HAS BEEN LOW KEY
AND WORKING THROUGH MANY
MEXICAN ATTORNEYS THAT THEY
HIRED TO TRY TO GET THEIR SON
FREE AND AFTER MONGS, THEY
HAVE GOT NO ACTION AND SO THEY
DECIDED TO TAKE THE GAMBLE AND
GO PUBLIC .
BOY, THIS STORY TOOK OFF .
WE CONTACTED THE STATE
DEPARTMENT AND OUR AMBASSADOR,
YOU NAME IT AND PRESIDENT
OBAMA, JANET NAACP, WE HAVE
REACHED OUT TO EVERYONE AND
THANKS TO OUR COLLEAGUES IN
CONGRESS.
30 MINUTES CO-STINED LETTERS
TO NAACP AND CLINTON,ING --
NAPAL TANIO TO BRING HIM HOME.
>> Gretchen: IT IS NOT LIKE
THE TALIBAN HAS HIM.
THIS IS COMMEXCO AND I
UNDERSTAND THE DRUG CARTELS
ARE IN CHARGE OF THE PRISONS
THERE.
DON'T WE HAVE GOOD ENOUGH
RELATIONS TO GET HIM HOME.
>> YOU WOULD THINK SO
ESPECIALLY WITH A BRAND NEW
PRESIDENT TAKING OVER .
WE HAVE SUPPOSEDLY GOOD
RELATIONS WITH OUR NEIGHBORS.
THEY ALSO LECTURE US ABOUT HOW
BADLY WE TREAT ILLEGAL
IMMIGRANTS WHICH IS BURCH OF A
BALONY AND YET THEY HAVE AN
AMERICAN HOAR INCARCERATED.
HE IS CHAINED TO HIS BED.
THIS IS TOLD TO ME BY MEXICAN
AUTHORITIES.
WHY ?
THEY HAD TO TAKE HIM OUT OF
THE GENERAL POPULATION AFTER
THE EXTORTIONS AND BEATINGS.
THEY HAVE HIM IN AN AREA AWAY
FROM THE GENERAL POPULATION.
THEY HAVE TO CHAIN THIS MARINE
TO THE BED TO MAKE SURE HE
WILL NOT ESCAPE.
IT IS UNBELIEVABLE THAT THE
MEXICAN GOVERNMENT IS NOT
STEPPING IN TO HELP US WHILE
THEY TAKE OUR MONEY AND HELP
WE GIVE THEM .
INCREDIBLE OUR OWN U.S.
GOVERNMENT IS NOT DOING ALL WE
CAN TO BRING HAMMER HOME FOR
CHRIS NAS.
HE'S DONE NOTHING WRONG.
>> Gretchen: SOUNDS LIKE YOU
ARE FRUSTRATED WITH OUR OWN
GOVERNMENT, AM I GETTING THAT
CORRECT ?
>> I DON'T WANT TO BE WHAT
JEAN KIRPATRICK WHO IS BLAME
THE AMERICAN.
OF COURSE IT IS THE MEXICAN
GOVERNMENT AT FAULT.
BUT THE U.S. GOVERNMENT HAS TO
SAY WE ARE NOT GOING TO GIVE
YOU A STATUS UPDATE ON JOHN
HAMMER, WE ARE GOING TO LOBBY
FOR HIS RELEASE AND GET HIM
AND IF THEY WANT TO GO THROUGH
A TRIAL, THAT IS FINE.
BOND HIM OUT.
HE SUFFERED WITH POST
TRAUMATIC STRESS AND SERVED IN
IRAQ AND AFGHANISTAN AND GOT
OUT OF A CLINIC TO DEAL WITH
STRESS AND NOW HE FINDS
HIMSELF.
IT IS UNFAIR AND UNJUST.
WE'LL KEEP ON FIGHTING.
WE'LL MAKE IT HAPPEN.
>> Gretchen: THANKS FOR YOUR
EFFORTS AND THANK YOU FOR
GETTING UP EARLY.
>> I APPRECIATE IT >>
Gretchen: I JUST TALKED ABOUT
THE TALIBAN, RIGHT.
THE TALIBAN'S MISSION TO KILL
AMERICANS, WHYURE OUR TROOPS
TOLD TO BE NICE TO THEM.
THEN IT IS IT A CHRISTMAS
TRYTREE LIKE YOU HAVE NEVER
SEEN BEFORE.
♪
ALL RIGHT.
IT IS IT A VIOLINIST, LOOK AT
150 KIDS STUFFED IN A TREE.
AMAZING, THAT STORY IS NEXT.
♪
I'M DOING MY OWN SLEEP STUDY.
ADVIL PM® OR TYLENOL PM.
THE ADVIL PM® GUY
IS SPENDING LESS TIME
LYING AWAKE
WITH ANNOYING ACHES AND PAINS
AND MORE TIME ASLEEP.
ADVIL PM®. THE DIFFERENCE
IS A BETTER NIGHT'S SLEEP.
Your soups are
so awesomely delicious
my husband and I
can't stop eating 'em!
What's...that...
on your head?
Can curlers!
Tomato basil.
Potato with bacon.
We've got
a lotta empty cans.
[ Male Announcer ] Hear from
our chefs on Facebook
this Friday!
I KNEW IT'D BE TOUGH
ON OUR RETIREMENT SAVINGS,
ESPECIALLY IN THIS ECONOMY.
BUT WITH THREE KIDS,
BEING HOME MORE REALLY HELPED.
Man:
SO WE WENT TO FIDELITY.
WE TALKED ABOUT WHERE WE WERE
AND WHAT WE COULD DO.
WE CHANGED OUR PLAN AND DID
SOMETHING ABOUT OUR ECONOMY.
NOW WE KNOW
WHERE TO GO FOR HELP
IF THINGS CHANGE AGAIN.
CALL OR COME IN TODAY
TO TAKE CONTROL
OF YOUR PERSONAL ECONOMY.
GET FREE ONE-ON-ONE HELP FROM
AMERICA'S RETIREMENT LEADER.
>> Steve: WE HAVE QUICK HEAD
LINES FOR YOU THIS MORNING.
COULD JENNY RIVERA AVOIDED SHE
MADE A LAST MINUTE DECISION TO
TAKE THE DEADLY PLANE RIDE.
SHE WAS OFFERED A ROOM FOR THE
NIGHT BUT INSTEAD DECIDE TOD
FLY.
A NEW DRAFT OF THE ARMY HAND
BOOK IS TELLING OUR SOLDIERS
TO BE NICE TO THEM.
OUR TOP COMMANDER GENERAL
ALLEN IS NOT HAPPY AND REFUSES
TO ENDORSE THE BOOK.
>> Gretchen: PEOPLE ARE TRYING
TO ERASE CHRISTMAS FROM OUR
CULTURE .
BUT ONE CHURCH IS GOT PEOPLE
SINGING FROM THE BRANCHES.
HERE'S MORE.
THIS IS A PERFECT STORE STORE
FOR YOU, TOD TOD.
YOU LIKE TO KEEP CHRISTMAS
ALIVE AS LIMP IT IS MEMP
ISTENSE TENSE MEMPHIS IS KNOWN
FOR ELVIS PRESLEY AND QUEUE
QUEUE ON THE PLANET AND AN
UNUSUAL CHRISTMAS TREE.
CHECK IT OUT.
THE REPUTATION FOR DOG BIG
THINGINGS .
THEY HAVE THREE BIG CROSSES
AND A BIG BIBLE VERSE AND A
BIG CONGREGATION AND A BIG
CHRISA MAS TREE.
♪
>> IT IS 44 FEET TALL AND OVER
100,000 LIGHTS ALL DRIVEN BY A
COMPUTER PROGRAM.
IT IS A MIDSOUTH HOLIDAY
TRADITION AND AROUND SINCE
1976 AND A CAST OF 400 PEOPLE
AND MANY ARE NOT OLD ENOUGH TO
DRIVE.
>> JUST THIS CHURCH AND WE
HAVE THE OPPORTUNITY TO DO
SOMETHING AS BIG AS
IT IS PRETTY COOL.
>> OKAY.
>> Steve: I AM IN THE BIG TREE
.
IT WAS LIKE CLIMBING THE
MATTER HORN AND I AM ONLY HALF
WAY UP THE SIZE OF THE
GIGANTIC SINGING CHRISTMAS
TREE.
THEY WILL HAVE 150 TEENS
STUFFED IN HERE.
RIGHT NOW I FEEL LIKE A GIANT
SWIRIL.
IT IS A YEAR ROUND VENTURE AND
HUNDREDS OF VOLUNTEERS WORK
BEHIND THE SCENES CREATING A
19TWENS VERSION OF NEW YORK
CITY THAT ENVY BROADWAY.
>> PEOPLE ENJOY PROGRAMS AND
GOOD FAM FAM VALUES AND
SOMETHING THEY CAN TAKE THEIR
FAM FAM, >> THIS IS NOT AN OLD
CHURCH SCHOOL BATH ROBES AND
NO FLAKE.
>> NO, NO, THIS IS IT A HUGE
PRODUCTION .
IT IS IT ALL CONTEMPARY AND
ALL DIFFERENT KINDS OF MUSIC
AND COSTUMES AND MAKE UP .
♪
ANDINE THOUGH THE SINGING
CHRISTMAS TREE IS IT BROADWAY
QUALITY THERE IS A MAJOR
DIFFERENCE.
>> WE HOPE THAT PEOPLE WILL
SEE A GREAT SHOW.
BUT WE TALK ABOUT IN THE
REHEARSALS T. IS NOT A SHOW
FOR SHOW'S SAKE BUT TELLING
THE PEOPLE GOOD NEWS OF JES
JES CHRIST.
IF THEY COME AND REMEMBER THE
NAME OF BELLEVIE AND A CAST
MEMBER, WE MISSED T. BUT IF
THEY REMEMBER THE NAME OF JES
JES CHRIST AND ACCEPT HIM IN
THEIR LIFE AND LET HIM CHANGE
THEIR LIVES.
FAM FAMS WOULD BE DIFFERENT
AND LIVES WOULD BE AND THAT'S
OUR HOPE.
THAT IS A BIG SHOW AND THIS IS
MOSTLY TEENAGERS AND YOUNG
PEOPLE THAT SPEND MONTHS
PREPARING FOR THE PECK
TACKULAR SHOW .
30,000 CAME TO TO WATCH T. >>
WHAT ABOUT THE TREE TOPPER.
>> USUALLY A MAUL PERSON .
CAN I GET UP THERE ?
YEAH, NO.
THAT IS NOT GOING TO HAPPEN .
>> IS THERE JUST ONE SHOW.
>> NO, IT IS IT A SERIES OF
THREE OR FOUR DAYS AND FOR
FOLKS WHO CANE MAKE THE
PERFORMANCE.
THEY HAVE A DVD.
IT IS GREAT FOLKS.
>> 28 MINUTES AFTER THE HOUR.
COMING UP NEXT, A COLLEGE
PROFESSOR ACCUSED OF TELLING
THE CLASS THAT THE MILITARY
HAD BLOOD ON THEIR HANDS.
WHAT HAPPENED TO THE PROFESSOR
FOR SAYING THAMPT >> Steve:
THE FED HAS A PLAN TO FIX OUR
ECONOMY.
REALLY IN STEWART VARNEY.
>> Gretchen: FIRST.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY TO CLIFF
WILLIAMS.
HE IS ROCKING IT ALL NIGHT
LONG.
♪
WAKING THE BABY.
[ coughs ]
[ baby crying ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
ROBITUSSIN® LIQUID FORMULA
SOOTHES YOUR THROAT ON CONTACT
AND THE ACTIVE INGREDIENT
RELIEVES YOUR COUGH.
ROBITUSSIN®. DON'T SUFFER
THE COUGHEQUENCES™.
♪ I DON'T WANNA BE RIGHT
[ record scratch ]
WHAT?! IT'S NOT BAD FOR YOU.
IT JUST TASTES THAT WAY.
[ Female Announcer ]
Honey Nut Cheerios CEREAL --
HEART-HEALTHY,
WHOLE GRAIN OATS.
YOU CAN'T GO WRONG LOVING IT.
TIME FOR CITI PRICE REWIND.
BECAUSE YOUR DAUGHTER REALLY
WANTS THAT PINK CASTLE THING.
AND YOU REALLDON'T WANT
TO PAY MORE THAN YOU HAVE TO.
ONLY CITI PRICE REWIND
AUTOMATICALLY SEARCHES
FOR THE LOWEST PRICE.
AND IF IT FINDONE, YOU GET
REFUNDED THE DIFFERENCE.
JUST USE YOUR CITI CARD
AND REGISTER YOUR PURCHASE
ONLINE.
HAVE A SUPER SPARKLY DAY!
OK.
[ Male Announcer ] NOW ALL
YOUEED IS A MAGIC CARRIAGE.
CITI PRICE REWIND.
START SAVING
AT CITI.COM/PRICEREWIND.
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
I'M GOING TO DREAM
ABOUT THAT STEAK.
ABOUT THAT TIRAMISU.
WHAT A NIGHT, HUH?
BUT, UM, CAN THE TEST DRIVE
BE OVER NOW?
HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A PASSAT.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN, $0 DUE AT SIGNING,
$0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
NESPRESSO.
WHERE I NEVER HAVE TO COMPROMISE
ON ANYTHING.
♪
WHERE JUST ONE TOUCH
CREATES THE PERFECT COFFEE.
WHERE EVERY CAPPUCCINO AND LATTE
IS ONLY MADE WITH FRESH MILK.
AND WHERE THE STAFF
IS EXCEPTIONALLY FRIENDLY.
♪
NESPRESSO. WHAT ELSE?
>> Gretchen: TIME FOR YOUR
SHOT OF THE MORE THANING.
HIS BEAVER LOOKS TO BE WAVING
RIGHT BACK.
>> Brian: LEAVE IT TO BEAVER.
>> Gretchen: THE BEAVER WE HAD
DIDN'T APPEAR BE AS FRIENDLY.
92 RIGHT.
>> Brian: I TELL YOU WHAT,
THAT BEAVER UPONS OUT AND NOT
HAPPY IN THE TANK.
>> Steve: LET'S TALK ABOUT THE
AMERICAN RIVER COLLEGE IN,
CALIFORNIA.
THEY WERE HAVING AN ART CLASS
AND THE PROFESSOR.
A FELLOW BY THE NAME OF TOM
WAS DISCUSSING AN ART
INSTALLATION, AND A VET RAN BY
THE NAME OF SHILOH DAVID
HELMAN AND THE PROFESSIONAL
SAW THE PARALLEL BETWEEN THE
BLOOD ON THE HANDS OF THE
DISPLAY AND THE BLOOD OF OUR
VET RANS.
MR. HELMAN TOOK FENCE FENCE
AND HE SAID THIS.
HE WAS A VET RAN.
>> HE TOLD ME I AM THE PROBLEM
WITH AMERICAN.
I GO TO DO A JOB AND DEF NATION.
AND THEN LEFT THE CLASS.
>> Brian: THIS IS NOT THE
FIRST TIME THE PROFESSOR WENT
OVER THE LINE AND JUST ABOUT
EVERYBODY'S WATCHING MIND.
THE RED RIVER AMERICAN COLLEGE
SAID WE ARE LOOKING BOO THE
ALLEGATION.
OUR COLLEGE GREVANCE OFFICER
IS MEETING FROM STUNES.
HE STOOD FOR SOMETHING JUST
LIKE HE THOUGHT FOR SOMETHING.
>> Gretchen: WHAT ABOUT
MEETING WITH THE PROFESSOR ?
>> Steve: I THINK THEY WANT TO
HEAR THEIR SIDE OF THE STORE
STORE AND WHAT HE SAID.
IF YOU GO TO RATE MY PROFESSOR
OPINION COM.
A SITE THEY USED.
THEY HAVE DESCRIBED HIM
LIBERAL AND DEROGATORY .
DON'T BE SURPRISED IF THE
STUDENTS COROB BRATE THE STORE
STORE - STORY OF THE VET.
>> Brian: ONE OF THE ONLY
LIVING MEDAL OF HONOR
RECIPIENTS.
DETAILS ON THE FIGHT OF DAKOTA
MYER.
AN 18 YEAR OLD WAS CHARGED
WITH ASSAULT.
MYER WAS AWARDED THE HIGHEST
HONOR BY PRESIDENT OBAMA LAST
YEAR AND CREDITED WITH SAVING
THE LIVES OF 23 AMERICANS AND
AFGHAN SOLDIERS IN A FIRE FOIT
IN 2009.
92 BEING OVERWEIGHT BE LINKED
TO THE WAY YOU WERE BORN.
RESEARCHERS LOOKED AT NINE
STUDIES OF OVER 200,000 PEOPLE
AND FOUND BEING BORN BY
C-SECTION BABIES WERE MORE
LIKELY TO BE HEAVY IN LIFE.
IT DOESN'T MEAN IT CAUSED THE
WEIGHT GAIN.
>> Brian: YOU ARE FOLLOWING
THAT STORE STORE.
>> Steve: ALL 200,000 PEOPLE.
>> Gretchen: THAT IS WEIRD.
>> Brian: NO BABIES COMMENTED.
>> Gretchen: THEY COULDN'T
SPEAK.
THE SHOW WILL NOT GO ON IN
MASSACHUSETTS.
THE HOLIDAY CONCERT IS CANCEL
WOULD AFTER LAST YEAR'S
PERFORMANCE WAS TOO RELIGIOUS.
I HAVEN'T HEARD THAMPT A
SPEECH ON 18-BULLYING, WILL
TAKE PLACE ON THE CONCERT IN
JANUARY.
REALLY?
>> Brian: HUGE GAME FOR THE
CINCINNATI BENGALS.
TURN OVERS WERE THE KEY
AGAINST THE EAGLES AND THEY
AGAIN WERE THEIR OWN WORST
ENEMY.
THEY GAVE THE BALL AWAY FIVE
TIMES.
THEY HAD A LOT OFITALENT.
THEY CAME BACK TO DO 34-13 AND
WILL FACE THE PITTSBURG
STEELERS NEXT WEEK.
WHAT COULD BE THE PLAYOFF
DECIDING CONTEST.
JETS STILL FANCY THEMSELVES IN
THE PLAYOFF HUNT.
>> Brian: FORMER TEX TEX
RANGER SLUGGER JOSH HAMILTON
HAS AGREED TO PLAY FOR THE LOS
ANGELES ANGELS.
SO MUCH TALENT ON THE WEST
COAST.
THE DOLE IS WORTH $125 MILLION
OVER THE NEXT FIVE YEARS.
HAMILTON DROVE IN 148 RBI'S.
HE HAS A HISTORY OF SUBSTANCE
ABUSE AND A BIT OF A STREAKY
PLAYER AND HAS TROUBLE
AVOIDING INJURY.
AND WE'LL SEE WHAT HAPPENS
NEXT.
>> Gretchen: ALSO A HISTORY OF
THE HOME RUNS.
ANGELS SAID -- RANGERS EXCUSE
ME SAID YOU CAN GO.
>> Steve: THE ECONOMY IS STILL
SPUTTERING AND THE FEDERAL
RESERVE HAS A PLAN TO GET IT
BACK ON TRACK.
>> NO, NO, NO.
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO IS HOOK THE
BAD BOY UP TO THE HOUSE AND
THROW THE CARD IN AND BOOM,
BOOM AND MOW, MONEY AND MORE
MONEY.
>> Steve: YEAH, MORE MONEY AND
CHAIRMAN BEN BERNANKE SAID THE
FED WILL PRINT MORE MONEY TO
PUSH DOWN INTEREST RATES.
WILL MORE MONEY MEAN MORE
PROBLEMS ?
NOTHING TO LAUGH ABOUT WHEN
YOU THINK OF WHAT THE
GOVERNMENT IS DOG.
PRINTING ALL OF THIS MONEY AND
TRYING TO GET IT -- WE ARE DOG
WHAT ?
>> THE NUMBERS ARE STAGGERING.
BEN BERNANKE IS GOING TO PRINT
A TRILLION A YEAR.
THIS IS IT THE FIFTH YEAR IN A
ROW HE PRINTED A TRILLION
BUCKS MEANWHILE, PRESIDENT
OBAMA IS GOING TO BORROW EYE
TRILLION DOLLARS THIS YEAR AND
THAT IS FOR THE FIFTH YEAR IN
A ROW THAT THEY BORROWED A
TRILLION.
YOU PRINTED A TRILLION AND
BORROWING A TRILIAN WHERE IS
IT GOING TO END ?
ODDS ARE YOU WILL HAVE A
FINANCIAL CRISIS.
INFLATION OR DEBT CRISIS.
IN THE IMMEDIATE FUTURE WE ARE
BUMLING ALONG WITH SLOW
GROWTH.
>> Steve: BEN BERNANKE SAID
THEY WILL CONTINUE TO KEEP
INTEREST LOW UNTIL
UNEMPLOYMENT GOT DOWN TO 6
PERCENT.
I KNOW YOU ARE A ECONANIST.
ISN'T THE BEST WAY TO GET
UNEMPLOYMENT LOWER TO GET MORE
JOBS.
>> THEY HAVE DONE THIS FOUR
YEARS AND IT HANE WORKED .
UNEMPLOYMENT RATE IS 7.7
PERCENT.
WHY ARE WE DOG IT ALL OVER
AGAIN WHEN IT HASN'T WORKED IN
THE PAST.
PEOPLE HAVE ZY --ANXIETY.
IT IS HANUKKAH AND CHRISTMAS.
AND DONE TALK ABOUT THE MONEY
BEING PRENTED.
BUT THERE IS AXIETY.
INFLATION OR DEBT CRISIS OR
SLOW GROWTH WITH CONTINUED
HIGH UNEMPLOYMENT.
NOT A PRETTY PICTURE.
>> Steve: MERRY CHRISTMAS
INDEED.
CHECK OUT STEWART'S SHOW AND
YOU CAN SEE HIM EVERY DAY ON
THE FOX NEWS CHANNEL PLATFORM
KNOWN AS FOX BUSINESS.
NTHANK YOU, STEVE .
>> Steve: 20 MINUTES BEFORE
THE TOP OF THE HOUR.
MENTIONING CHRISTMAS JUST IN
TIME.
LATE-BREAKING DEOF A STRIKE.
HOW IS THIS FOR A CHRISTMAS
CARD.
THAT IS NANCY REAGAN AND
MR. T.
I REMEMBER THAMPT THE STORE
STORE AND MANY MORE.
♪
THAT'S RIGHT.
I'VE LEARNED THE ONLY WAY TO GET
A HOLIDAY DEAL IS TO CAMP OUT.
YOU KNOW WE'VE BEEN OPEN
ALL NIGHT.
IS THIS A TRICK
TO GET MY SPOT?
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SAVE ON GROUND SHIPPING
AT FEDEX OFFICE.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
YOU CAN'T ARGUE WITH
NUTRITION YOU CAN SEE.
GREAT GRAINS.
GREAT GRAINS CEREAL STARTS
WHOLE AND STAYS WHOLE.
SEE THE SEAM?
MORE PCESSED FLAKES LOOK
NOTHING LIKE NATURAL GRAINS.
I'M EATING WHAT I KN
IS BETTER NUTRITION.
MMMM. GREAT GRAINS.
SEARCH GREAT GRAINS
AND SEE FOR YOURSELF.
TO COME HOME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE...
SADLY, THEIR BROTHER'S
WHITE CHRISTMAS
JUST GOT "BLACKED OUT."
[ Brother ]
BUT IT'S THE FAMILY PARTY!
REALLY JINGLES YOUR BELLS,
DOESN'T IT?
MY GIFT TO YOU!
THE Capital One Venture Card!
FOR ANY FLIGHT, ANY TIME!
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE!
HOW ILLUMINATING.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
LET ME GUESS, AM
ON THE NAUGHTY LIST AGAIN?
HO HO HO!
Your soups are
so awesomely delicious
my husband and I
can't stop eating 'em!
What's...that...
on your head?
Can curlers!
Tomato basil.
Potato with bacon.
We've got
a lotta empty cans.
[ Male Announcer ] Hear from
our chefs on Facebook
this Friday!
>> Gretchen: 44 MINUTES AFTER
THE TOP OF THE HOUR.
HAPPENS OF PRIVATE SECURITY
WORKERS IN NEW YORK JFK
AIRPORT THREATENING TO WALK
OFF IF DEMANDS ARE NOT MET.
LIDIA HAS MORE WITH WHAT THIS
COULD MEAN FOR HOLIDAY
TRAVELERS.
THIS ALWAYS HAPPENS .
IT IS LEVERAGE TIME FOR IT TO
HAPPEN NOW, RIGHT.
>> JUST FIVE DAYS BEFORE
CHRISTMAS.
DECEMBER 20TH.
THAT'S WHEN THE WORKERS
AUTHORIZED A STRIKE.
THEY ARE NONUNION WORKERS AND
WORK FOR TWO SEPARATE
COMPANIES AND WORKERS FOR ONE
OF THE COMPANIES AUTHORIZED
THE STRIKE.
THE SECOND COMPANY IS VOTING
ON WHETHER TO AUTHORIZE A
STRIKE.
JFK IS ONE OF THE BIGGEST IN
THE COUNTRY.
42 MILLION PEOPLE ARE SCHEDULE
WOULD TO FLY AROUND THE
HOLIDAY SEASON.
IT COULDN'T COME AT A WORSE
TIME .
WE SPOKE TO THE TRAVELERS THAT
ARE WORRIED.
THEY ACTUALLY THE TRAFFIC HERE
IN THE TERMINAL AND GUARD
ALARM DOORS AND SO MANY PEOPLE
ARE WORRIED ABOUT THIS .
WORKERS SAY THEY ARE UNDERPAID
AND HAVE THE PROPER ECONOMY.
THAT IS THE LATEST.
FOX NEWS.
BACK TO YOU.
>> THANK YOU FOR THAT REPORT.
>> Steve: NOW TO THE WHITE
WHOIT.
HALLS ARE DECK WOULD JUST IN
TIME FOR CHRISTMAS.
>> Brian: THIS YEAR MICHELLE
OBAMA DECORATED WITH THE THEME
OF JOY TO ALL .
THERE ARE CHRISTMAS TREES
HONORING PAST FIRST LADY AND
HOW THEY SPEN TIME IN THE
WHITE HOUSE.
>> Gretchen: CAN YOU IMAGINE.
JOINING US A WOMAN WHO WAS
PART OF THE 2008 DECORATING
TEAM AND AUTHOR OF CHRISTMAS
WITH THE FIRST LADY.
CHOLINE, GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
I LOVE GOING THROUGH IT IT
BRINGS YOU BACK IN TIME AND
EACH FIRST LADY UPONED TO
CREATE THEIR OWN IDENITY.
>> THEY HAD THEIR SIGNATURE
STYLE AND MESSAGE TO SEND TO
THE AMERICAN PUBLIC AT
CHRISTMAS .
THIS YEAR MRS. OBAMA IS JOY TO
ALL SHE ALWAYS REMEMBERS THE
SERVICEMEN AND WOMEN SERVING
IN THE ARMED FORCES.
>> Steve: THERE IS IT A
BEAUTIFUL CHRISTMAS TREE THAT
CAME IN ON A HORSE DRAWN
WAGON.
>> A TINY LITTLE >> Steve:
THEY HAVE 54 CHRISTMAS TREES
AND THE DECORATORS USED YOUR
BOOKS TO HELP FIGURE OUT HOW
TO DO IT >> THEY CAN A TRIBUTE
TO THE FIRST LADY EXERCISE
PULLED OUT A LOT OF SOURCE
MATERIAL.
THEY HAVE BEEN AMAZING
THROUGHOUT THE YEARS AND THE
DECORATIONS ARE AWESOME.
>> Brian: GOING BACK FOR
JACKIE KENNEDY.
>> SHE SAID IF WE ARE HAVING
PEOPLE OVER FOR THE HOLIDAYS .
SHE WENT FOR THE NUT CRACKER
AND HAD TINY ORNAMS.
THAT IS DIFFERENT.
>> Gretchen: WHAT ABOUT BETTY
FORD ?
>> HER IDEA WAS TO HAVE A
THRIFTY HOLIDAY AND WANTED
CALICO FABRIC AND SHE SPENT
MORE MONEY.
CENT 1600 DOLLARS AND THE
PRESS WAS TOUGH ON HER WHICH
IS FUBY WHEN WE LOCK AT HOW
MUCH THEY SPENT TODAY.
>> Steve: I REMEMBER IN THE
REAGAN TERM.
MRS. REAGAN USED TO HAVE
CELEBRITY SECRET SANTAS >> SHE
WAS.
SHE WAS ALL ABOUT GLITS AND
GLAMOUR AND THIS WHITE HOUSE
IS WHAT YOU WANTED TO SO.
SHE HAD MR. T AND LARRY HAGMAN
WAS A CELEBRITY SANT A. >>
THERE IS MR. T.
>> Gretchen: AND FINALLY LAURA
BUSH.
YOU WERE INSTRUMENTAL TO
HELPING .
>> SHE INVITED ME TO BE A PART
OF THE DECORATING TEAM.
IT WAS ELEGANCE AND BEING
UNDERSTATED AND RED, WHITE AND
BLUE CHRISTMAS AND
INCORPORATED BOOKS AND STORIES
AND MADE IT ENCHANTING FOR
CHILDREN.
IT IS CHRISTMAS WITH THE FIRST
LADIES AND BEAUTIFUL STORIES
AND PICTURES AS WELL.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
HAVING ME.
>> Gretchen: MERRY CHRISTMAS.
>> Steve: THIEVES TRY TO RIP
OFF A CHURCH AND GET A SHOCK
INSTEAD.
>> Brian: HIGH SCHOOL
BASKETBALL TEAM ENDS WITH A
SCORE OF 107-2 .
THE COACH OF THE LOSING TEAM
IS HERE NEXT.
♪
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Sharable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>> Gretchen: ED.
>> Brian: INDIANA GIRL'S
BASKETBALL TEAM SCORED BIG ON
TUESDAY NIGHT.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN REALLY BIG?
THEY WON A GAME 107-2.
NOW PARENTS ON THE LOSING SIDE
WANT TO KNOW WHY WASN'T THE GAME
CALLED OFF SOONER?
WHY WASN'T BETTER SPORTSMANSHIP
SHOWN PERHAPS BY THE WINNING
TEAM?
BOB IS THE ATHLETIC DIRECTOR AT
ARLINGTON HIGH SCHOOL THAT,
SCHOOL THAT LOST BIG TIME.
SO THANK YOU FOR JOINING US,
BOB.
ARE YOU UPSET WITH BLOOMINGTON
SOUTH?
>> THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
AS A SCHOOL WE HOLD NO HARD
FEELINGS TOWARD BLOOMINGTON
SOUTH.
THE WAY WE LOOK AT IT NOW OUR
GIRL'S BASKETBALL PROGRAM IS AT
THE VERY BEGINNING STAGES OF
DEVELOPMENT.
WE CURRENTLY HAVE TEN GIRLS IN
THE WHOLE PROGRAM.
SIX OF THOSE TEN ARE PLAYING
BASKETBALL ALL TOGETHER FOR THE
FIRST TIME IN THEIR LIFE.
I'M NOT TALKING BEING ON A TEAM,
REALLY JUST PLAYING THE GAME FOR
THE FIRST TIME.
BLOOMINGTON SOUTH, YEAR IN AND
YEAR OUT IS A STATE POWER.
CURRENTLY THEY'RE 8-1.
RANKED NUMBER 10 IN THE STATE.
SO WE DEFINITELY -- WE JUST SEE
IT AS TWO PROGRAMS THAT ARE
ABOUT ON POLAR OPPOSITE ENDS IN
THE SPECTRUM.
>> Brian: I WOULD SAY SO, BUT I
THINK THERE'S A LOT OF TEAMS
SUBSTANTIALLY BETTER THAN THEIR
OPPONENTS.
THEY DON'T WIN BY 105 POINTS.
WOULD YOU BE DISPINT FUNDAMENTAL
A TEAM UNDER INJURE JURISDICTION
WON BY 105?
WOULD YOU ANGRY AT THAT COACH?
>> WELL, I MEAN, WE TRUST
BLOOMINGTON SOUTH AND THEY'RE
COACHING STAFF ABOUT ALL THEY
COULD OUTRIGHT KEEP THE
INTEGRITY AND THE SPORTSMANSHIP
THE BEST THEY CAN.
YOU KNOW, THERE ARE THINGS THAT
YOU CAN DO, LIKE TAKING PRESS
PRESTONS OFF AND WE FEEL THEY
DID A DECENT JOB OF.
>> Brian: WOW.
>> WE DON'T HOLD ANY HARD
FEELINGS TOWARD THEM.
WE LOOK AT IT AS AN OPPORTUNITY
FOR OUR GIRLS TO SEE IF A
PROGRAM LIKE BLACKTON SOUTH,
ENTRY THEY ARE.
>> Brian: THEY SAW A LOT OF THAT
PROGRAM.
HERE IS WHAT THE COACH SAID.
BOTH TEAMS PLAYED HARD.
TO DO ANYTHING LESS BY EITHER
TEAM WOULD HAVE BEEN DEMEANING.
ARLINGTON CAME OUT AND WORKED ON
THEIR PLAYER DEVELOPMENT AS DID
WE.
THE LONG STANDING REPUTATION OF
OUR PROGRAM AND COACH IS ONE
THAT WOULD VALIDATE THIS
INFORMATION.
SAYING IT WOULD BE MORE OF AN
INSULT IF WE STOPPED SHOOTING.
DO YOU AGREE WITH THAT?
>> TO A CERTAIN EX AT ANY TIME,
YEAH.
I MEAN, AGAIN, WHERE DO YOU DRAW
THAT LINE OF TRYING NOT TO SCORE
AS MOCKING THE OPPONENT AND
EMBARRASSING THEM?
I THINK ONE THING YOU COULD LOOK
AT IS THE CHARACTER OF OUR YOUNG
LEADERS.
THAT SCORE BOARD IS UP THERE ALL
NIGHT FOR 32 MINUTES AND JUST
LIKE THE PEOPLE SAID, OUR GIRLS
PLAYED HARD TORE 32 MINUTES.
IT'S EASY FOR THEM.
>> Brian:   THE COACH OF YOUR
TEAM SAID THEY COULD HAVE SHOWN
BETTER RESPONSEMANSHIP.
I THINK THAT'S THE LEAST, DON'T
YOU THINK.
>> AFTER A LOSS LIKE THAT, YOU
SPEAK -- WE'RE TAKING IT AS
WE'RE JUST GOING TO FOCUS ON US
AND OUR GIRLS BASKETBALL
PROGRAM.
WE'RE EXTREMELY PROUD OF THEM
AND THE EFFORT THEY GAVE THAT
NIGHT AND THE FACT THAT THEY
DIDN'T QUIT.
THEY'RE A RESILIENT GROUP OF
YOUNG LADIES.
WE'RE NOT FOCUSED ON THE
NEGATIVE.
>> Brian: YOU GOT TO MAYBE GET
TOGETHER WITH OTHER ATHLETIC
DIRECTORS AND TALK ABOUT THINGS
LIKE A MERCY RULE PERHAPS.
DOWN BY 50 AT THE HALF.
>> RIGHT.
YEAH.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
OR POSSIBLY THE IDEA OF RUNNING
THE CLOCK ONCE YOU GET TO A
CERTAIN SPREAD.
HERE IN INDIANA WE HAVE THE
GOVERNING BODY WHICH WILL WORK
TIGHT WILL HE WITH OUR COACHES.
THESE ARE GREAT CONVERSATIONS
MOVING FORWARD.
WE HOLD NO HARD FEELINGS TOWARD
BLOOMINGTON SOUTH.
IT'S GREAT OPPORTUNITY FOR US TO
IMPROVE.
>> Brian: OKAY.
IF YOU'RE UP BY 90 AGAINST THEM,
I WANT YOU TO STOP YOUR GIRLS
FROM SCORING NEXT TIME AROUND.
BOB, THANKS SO MUCH AND GOOD
LUCK WITH DEVELOPING THE PROGRAM
AND THE STANCE YOU GUYS HAVE
TAKEN AND GOOD LUCK TO YOUR
GIRLS.
>> THANK YOU FOR HAVING US.
APPRECIATE IT.
>> Brian: THANKS.
GOOD LUCK THIS SEASON.
STRAIGHT AHEAD, YOU'VE SEEN THIS
PICTURE ON FOX NEWS CHANNEL.
BUT ARE THE OTHER NETWORKS
COVERING THE UNION VIOLENCE OUT
OF MICHIGAN?
WE'LL AND THE FACTS AND DO SO
MUCH MORE IN THE FINAL TWO HOURS
OF THIS WEEK ON "FOX & FRIENDS"
Wow.
It's the honey,
it makes it taste so...
Well, would you
look at the time...
What's the rush?
Be happy. Be healthy.
they see more than themselves.
look in the mirror,
What's the rush?
So we celebrate our year-end
with the "share the love" event.
Get a great deal on a new Subaru
and 250 dollars goes to your
choice of five charities.
By the end of this, our fifth
year,
our total can reach almost 25
million dollars.
It's a nice reflection on us
all.
Now through January 2nd.
Get 0% APR financing for 36
months on a 2013 Subaru Forester
and we'll donate 250 dollars to
your choice of 5 charities.
NESPRESSO.
WHERE I NEVER HAVE TO COMPROMISE
ON ANYTHING.
♪
WHERE JUST ONE TOUCH
CREATES THE PERFECT COFFEE.
WHERE EVERY CAPPUCCINO AND LATTE
IS ONLY MADE WITH FRESH MILK.
AND WHERE THE STAFF
IS EXCEPTIONALLY FRIENDLY.
♪
NESPRESSO. WHAT ELSE?
LET'FOR AN IDEA.S -
A GRAND IDEA CALLED AMERICA.
THE IDEA THAT
IF YOU WORK HARD,
IF YOU HAVE A DREAM,
IF YOU WORK WITH
YOUR NEIGHBORS...
YOU CAN DO MOST ANYTHING.
THIS LED TO OTHER IDEAS
LIKE LERTY
AND ROCK 'N' ROLL.
TO FREE MARKETS,
FREE ENTERPRISE,
AND FREE REFILLS.
IT PUT A MAN ON THE MOON
AND A PHONE IN YOUR POCKET.
OUR COUNTRY'S GONE THROUGH A LOT
OVER THE CENTURIES AND A HALF.
BUT THIS IDEA ISN'T FRAGILE.
WHEN TIMES GET TOUGH,
IT RALLIES US AS ONE.
EVERY DAY, MORE PEOPLE
BELIEVE IN THE AMERICAN IDEA
AND WHEN THEY DO,
THE DREAM COMES TRUE.
WE'RE GRATEFUL
TO BE A PART OF IT.
>> Gretchen: TGIF.
IT'S SO GREAT TO GET TO FRIDAY
SOMETIMES, ISN'T IT?
DECEMBER 14, 2012.
I'M GRETCHEN CARLSON.
THANKS FOR SHARING YOUR TIME.
YOU CAN COUNT HER OUT.
AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE TELLING
THE PRESIDENT TO WITHDRAW HER
NAME FOR CONSIDERATION FOR
SECRETARY OF STATE.
BUT WHY NOW AFTER SHE HELD TWO
MEETINGS WITH GOP SENATORS?
IS IT BECAUSE THERE IS ANOTHER
REPORT POSSIBLY COMING OUT?
LOTS TO DISCUSS THIS MORNING.
>> Brian: THE PRESIDENT AND THE
SPEAKER MEET TO TALK ABOUT THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
BUT ARE THEY GETTING ANYWHERE?
>> I'M BEGINNING TO THINK THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S POSITION IS
LIKE MICHAEL CORLEONE, MY OFFER
IS NOTHING.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Brian: IS THAT REALLY THE
PRESIDENT'S PLAN AND BETTER YET,
IS IT WORKING?
>> Steve: MEANWHILE, THIS IS
WHAT YOU GET FOR TRYING TO RIP
OFF A CHURCH, A REAL SHOCKER.
WAS IT PERHAPS A CASE OF DIVINE
INTERVENTION?
"FOX & FRIENDS" HOUR TWO FOR
FRIDAY STARTS RIGHT NOW.
>> THIS IS CHRIS JEWEL, CAMERA 4
OPERATOR AND I SAY MERRY
CHRISTMAS TO YOU AND YOU'RE
WATCHING "FOX & FRIENDS."
>> Gretchen: ALL RIGHT.
TODAY IS THE DAY TO HONOR OUR
CREW.
ALL THESE FABULOUS GUYS, FOR THE
MOST PART GUYS, WHO OPERATE OUR
CAMERAS AND THERE IS CHRIS
CHULO.
WHAT WE CALL THE GIB.
THAT CAMERA MOVES ALL AROUND,
CAMERA 4.
MOVE IT UP AND DOWN.
>> Steve: HE HAVE HAS NO IDEA
HOW TO OPERATE IT.
>> Brian: BY THE WAY, WE ASK WHO
IS THE WEAKEST CAMERA MAN AND
GIVE HIM THIS CAMERA AND CHRIS
CHULO --
[ LAUGHTER ]
OH, OH.
>> Gretchen: GET HIM!
GET HIM!
>> Steve: HOW LONG YOU BEEN ON
THIS SHOW?
ALMOST FROM THE GET GO.
GREAT TO HAVE YOU.
>> Brian: HE DOESN'T GET PAID.
HE DOES IT FOR EXPERIENCE.
>> Gretchen: YEAH RIGHT.
WITH ALL THAT EXPERIENCE, MAYBE
HE COULD BECOME SECRETARY OF
STATE.
UNFORTUNATELY, SUSAN RICE WON'T
BE SECRETARY OF STATE.
YESTERDAY IN AN OP ED SHE TOOK
HERSELF OUT OF THE RUNNING.
THE TIMING IS INTERESTING 'CAUSE
THERE IS REPORTS THAT MAYBE A
BIG REPORT IS COMING OUT ON
ACTUALLY WHAT HAPPENED, THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE MIGHT TIME FEE
FIND OUT WHAT HAPPENED IN
BENGHAZI OF THE SHE WENT ON THE
SUNDAY TALK SHOWS, FIVE OF THEM,
A COUPLE OF DAYS AFTER THE
SEPTEMBER 11 ATTACKS AND SAID
THAT IT WAS A SPONTANEOUS
ATTACK.
EVEN THOUGH NOW IT'S BECOME
CLEAR SHE AND OTHERS PROBABLE
WILL HE KNEW THAT IT WAS
TERRORISM.
>> Steve: IN FACT, AFTER IT HIT
THE FAN, WE PREDICTED ON THIS
PROGRAM THAT SHE EVENTUALLY
WOULD BE WITHDRAWN BECAUSE SHE
SIMPLY WAS NOT WORTH THE FIGHT
AT THIS POINT AND YESTERDAY IN
HER OP ED IN THE PAGE OF THE
"WASHINGTON POST," SHE
ESSENTIALLY SAID THAT, NOT WORTH
TROUBLE.
SHE SAID ON SEPTEMBER 16 WHEN
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON WAS UNAVAILABLE AFTER A
GRUELING WEEK, THE WHITE HOUSE
ASKED ME TO APPEAR ON FIVE
SUNDAY TALK SHOWS WHEN
DISCUSSING BENGHAZI.
I RELIED ON FULLY CLEARED,
UNCLASSIFIED POINTS PROVIDED BY
THE INTEL COMMUNITY, ALTHOUGH
SHE KNEW THE SECRET STUFF,
WHICH ENCAPSULATED THEIR BEST
CURRENT ASSESS AM.
THESE UNCLASSIFIED POINTS
WERE --
>> Brian: WERE YOU FOLLOWING THE
WHITE ON THOSE HIGHLIGHTED OR
FOLLOWING YOU?
>> Steve: IT WAS THAT PERFECT.
>> Brian: THAT WAS THE BOUNCING
BALL.
THE PRESIDENT SAID WHILE I DEEP
WILL HE REGREAT THE UNFAIR AND
MISLEADING ATTACKS ON AMBASSADOR
RICE, IT REFLECTS HER CHARACTER.
CHAFFETZ SAYS COINCIDENCE?
I DON'T THINK SO.
THE STATE DEPARTMENT OWES US A
REPORT.
THAT'S WHY I THINK SUSAN RICE
MADE THAT ANNOUNCEMENT TODAY.
YOU'RE STARTING TO SEE THE
DEPARTMENT SQUIRM A LITTLE.
THEY'RE SAYING MAYBE WE'LL GIVE
YOU A SUMMARY.
SECRETARY CLINTON MAY NOT COME
UP.
I THINK THE REPORT, IF DONE
ACCURATELY, WILL BE A VERY
DIFFICULT THING FOR THE WHITE
HOUSE, THE STATE DEPARTMENT, THE
DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE AND THE
C.I.A. TO EXPLAIN.
>> Gretchen: THERE IS A LOT OF
MOVING PARTS THAT WERE HAPPENING
YESTERDAY AFTERNOON.
FIRST OF ALL, IT STARTED COMING
OUT THAT HILLARY CLINTON MAY BE
WOULDN'T TESTIFY ON DECEMBER 20
AS PLANNED.
MOMENTS LATER, SUSAN RICE TAKES
HERSELF OUT OF THE RUNNING.
ONE OF THE MAIN REASONS
POTENTIALLY THAT THIS REPORT IS
COMING OUT, REMEMBER, SUSAN RICE
EXTENDED THE OLIVE GRANT AND MET
WITH SENATOR LINDSEY GRAHAM AND
JOHN MCCAIN, HER TWO FIERCEST
CRITICS.
SHE THEN MET WITH SENATOR SUSAN
COLLIN A MODERATE.
SHE ALSO CAME OUT OF THE MEETING
SAYING, I ACTUALLY HAVE MORE
QUESTIONS NOW THAN I DID BEFORE.
SO IF YOU COULDN'T GET THE
MODERATE REPUBLICAN TO VOTE FOR
YOU FOR SECRETARY OF STATE, THE
WRITING WAS PROBABLY ON THE
WALL.
>> Brian: WHAT I THOUGHT WAS
TOTALLY OUT OF BOUNDS WITH
ANDREA MITCHELL SAID YESTERDAY
IN HER EVALUATION AND ANALYZING
WHAT THIS MEANS IN TERMS OF
POLITICS WITH HER BACKING OUT,
SHE BROUGHT UP THE GENDER FACTOR
AND THE RACE FACTOR.
LISTEN.
>> I THINK THAT THIS HAD BECOME
SORT OF AN IMPOSSIBLE CHALLENGE
FOR HER TO BE CONFIRMED.
SHE REALIZED THAT.
THE WHITE HOUSE REALIZED IT AS
WELL.
I THINK THEY KNOW THAT THEY ARE
ON GOOD POLITICAL, SOLID GROUND,
AS YOU WERE POINTING OUT.
THIS IS NOT GOING TO HEPARINS AT
ALL, THE FACT THAT A WOMAN AND A
WOMAN OF COLOR HAS BEEN FORCED
OUT OF THE CONFIRMATION PROCESS
BEFORE SHE WAS NOMINATED.
>> Gretchen: NOTHING TO DO WITH
IT.
>> Steve: LOOK, IT WAS GEORGE W
BUSH, A REPUBLICAN, WHO PLACED
IN THE JOB OF SECRETARY OF STATE
A WOMAN OF COLOR, CONDOLEEZA
RICE.
WE HAVE SEEN THIS A LOT, THIS
KIND OF TALK FROM THE LEFT OVER
THE LAST COUPLE OF MONTHS.
>> Gretchen: IT'S INTERESTING
BECAUSE IF ANYONE IS A PROPONENT
OF WOMEN SEEKING OFFICE IT'S ME.
I DON'T AGREE WITH ANDREA
MITCHELL AT ALL ON THIS.
WHEN YOU LOOK BACK AT RECENT
SECRETARY OF STATES, A LOT HAVE
BEEN WOMEN AND AFRICAN-AMERICAN.
YOU HAVE MADELEINE ALBRIGHT,
HILLARY CLINTON, CONDOLEEZA
RICE, I CAN'T EVEN REMEMBER THE
LAST MALE.
THEN YOU BROUGHT IT UP THAT IT
WAS COLIN POWELL.
I'M NOT SURE IT HAS ANYTHING O
DO WITH WHY SUSAN RICE WILL NOT
BE SECRETARY OF STATE.
>> Steve: IT ABSOLUTELY DOES
NOT.
SHE WENT OUT AND MANY PEOPLE
FEEL SHE LIED TO THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE TO GIVE THE PRESIDENT OF
THE UNITED STATES POLITICAL
COVER JUST BEFORE AN ELECTION.
>> Brian: 17 DAYS AND THREE DAYS
TO WRITE LEGISLATION.
PROBABLY LESS THAN 17 DAYS 'TIL
WE HIT THE FISCAL CLIFF.
THE PRESIDENT INVITED THE
SPEAKER TO THE WHITE HOUSE
YESTERDAY AND OUR E-MAIL BOX,
WE'RE GETTING FILLED UP.
THERE COMES THE SPEAKER AND
THERE GOES THE SPEAKER.
IT LASTED AN HOUR AND 15
MINUTES.
DID ANYTHING GET IRONED OUT?
SO FAR INSIDERS SAY NO.
YAO GOLDBERG OFFERED THIS
ANALYSIS AND IT WAS PRETTY
BRILLIANT.
>> I'M BEGINNING TO THINK THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S POSITION IS
LIKE MICHAEL CORLEONE'S POSITION
IN GODFATHER 2, MY OFFER IS
NOTHING.
HIS REAL GOAL IS WATCH THE
REPUBLICAN PARTY GO UP IN FLAMES
AND EAT THEMSELVES ALIVE.
WHICH SO FAR SEEMS TO BE
WORKING.
I THINK THAT WHAT BOEHNER TRIED
TO DO AT THIS POINT IS SIMPLY
TAKE THE MIDDLE CLASS TAX CUTS
AS PERMANENT,  WHICH WOULD BE A
HUGE CONSERVATIVE VICTORY, EAT
IT ON THE RAISING THE TOP RATES,
AND THEN LIVE TO FIGHT ANOTHER
DAY.
>> Steve: OKAY.
SO THAT'S JONAH GOLDBERG'S
OPINION, THAT MR. BOEHNER SHOULD
CAVE AND SAY OKAY, LET'S GO
AHEAD AND RAISE UP RATES.
YESTERDAY IN THEIR VERY BRIEF
CONVERSATION LESS THAN AN HOUR,
APPARENTLY THE PRESIDENT -- I'M
GOING TO PARAPHRASE WHAT WE
KNOW -- THE PRESIDENT SAID OKAY,
JOHN, YOU READY TO CAVE?
HE SAID NOPE, I'M NOT GOING TO
RAISE TAXES ON ANYBODY.
HOW THAT LASTED AN HOUR, I DON'T
KNOW.
>> Gretchen: BECAUSE IT REALLY
COMES DOWN TO WHETHER OR NOT THE
PRESIDENT IS ALSO GOING TO AGREE
TO SPENDING CUTS.
REMEMBER, FOLKS, ABOUT TWO YEARS
AGO HE SAID THAT HE WAS IN FAVOR
OF RAISING THE AGE OF MEDICARE
TO 67 FROM 65.
SO WHERE HAS THAT PRESIDENT
GONE?
NOW AT A MOST CRUCIAL MOMENT
WHEN LET'S FACE IT, IN ORDER TO
GET A DEAL DONE, BOTH SIDES ARE
GOING TO HAVE TO GIVE IN ON
STUFF THAT THEY DON'T WANT TO
GIVE IN ON.
IF THEY WANT TO MAKE A DEAL, OR
THE OTHER OPTION IS JUST GO OVER
THE CLIFF.
>> Steve: THE PROBLEM IS, DICK
DURBIN SAID YESTERDAY VERY
CLEARLY, UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES
ARE WE GOING TO RAISE THE
MEDICARE RETIREMENT AGE.
NANCY PELOSI ESSENTIALLY SAID
EXACTLY THE SAME THING.
SO TWO OF THE STRONGEST PEOPLE
IN THE SENATE AND THE HOUSE SAY
NO TO THE PRESIDENT, THERE IS
NOT A LOT OF WIGGLE ROOM THERE.
>> Brian: THE PRESIDENT DID A
MORNING SHOW INTERVIEW YESTERDAY
ON THE WEST COAST AND SAID THAT
JOHN BOEHNER WAS TOO CONCERNED
ABOUT RAISING TAX, ABOUT WHAT
REPUBLICANS WOULD SAY IF HE
RAISED TAXES.
>> Steve: IT CONTINUES.
>> Gretchen: FOX NEWS ALERT NOW,
TWO LARGE BACK TO BACK QUAKES
SHAKING THE CALIFORNIA COAST
THIS MORNING.
6.4 MAGNITUDE QUAKE ROCKED THE
SOUTHWEST COAST NEAR BAHA, JUST
ABOUT AN HOUR AGO.
MOMENTS LATER, A 6.1 QUAKE
STRUCK, SHAKING SAN DIEGO AND
LOS ANGELES.
SO FAR NO REPORTS OF ANY DAMAGE
OR INJURY.
>>> THE UNITED STATES RAMPING UP
ITS INVOLVEMENT IN THE CRISIS IN
SYRIA NOW.
OVERNIGHT DEFENSE SECRETARY LEON
PANETTA SIGNING OFF ON SEND TO
GO PATRIOT MISSILES AND 400
TROOPS TO TURKEY.
THAT'S TO HELP BEEF UP THE
COUNTRY'S DEFENSE AGAINST
POTENTIAL SYRIAN ATTACKS.
THE MISSILES WILL BE UNDER NATO
CONTROL.
>>> TODAY'S DECISION DEADLINE
FOR STATES TO DECIDE IF THEY'RE
GOING TO SET UP THEIR OWN
INSURANCE EXCHANGES UNDER
OBAMACARE.
RIGHT NOW 24 STATES HAVE OPTED
OUT.
19, INCLUDING THE DISTRICT OF
COLUMBIA, WILL HAVE THE
STATE-RUN EXCHANGES.
SIX STATES PLAN ON SPLITTING IT
WITH THE FEDS.
UTAH AND FLORIDA ARE THE ONLY IT
WHO HAVE NOT MADE A DECISION.
>>> TALK ABOUT DIVINE
INTERVENTION, CHECK THIS OUT.
TWO THIEVES LEARNING A PAINFUL
LESSON WHILE TRYING TO ROB A
CHURCH IN HOUSTON.
THEY TRIED GRABBING THE ELECTRIC
CABLE, LIKELY FOR ITS COPPER.
AND SET OFF THIS EXPLOSION.
COPS SAY THESE GUYS WON'T BE
HARD TO FIND.
THEIR INJURIES SHOULD BE A GIVE
AWAY.
THOSE ARE YOUR HEADLINES.
WHAT WILL THEIR INJURIES BE?
BURN MARKS?
>> Brian: I'M NOT SURE.
>> Steve: YEAH.
NEAR ELECTROCUTION.
ALTHOUGH THE THEFT OF COPPER
WIRE IS PRETTY RAMPANT BECAUSE
COP SERVICE QUITE VALUABLE THESE
DAYS.
>> Brian: TEN MINUTES AFTER THE
HOUR.
YOU'VE SEEN THIS PICTURE ON FOX
NEWS CHANNEL OVER AND OVER
BEGUN, STEVEN CROWDER GETTING
PUNCHED OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
BUT ARE THE OTHER NETWORKS
COVERING THE UNION VIOLENCE OUT
OF MICHIGAN?
WE'LL AND THE FACTS NEXT.
>> Steve: THEN DOES SHE LOOK
LIKE A TERRORIST TO YOU?
A LITTLE GIRL BROUGHT TO TEARS
BY THE AIRPORT PEOPLE
WANNA SEE ME
GET SOME GREAT DEALS?
OK!
IT'S A NEW WAY
TO GET CASH BACK DEALS
AND IT'S CALLED BANKAMERIDEALS.
I SIGN IN
TO MY ONLINE BANKING...
CLICK THE "CASH BACK DEALS"
TAB...
AND PICK THE DEALS I WANT.
JUST USE MY BANK OF AMERICA
DEBIT OR CREDIT CARD WHEN I PAY.
AND THEN I GET
UP TO 15% CASH BACK...
PUT INTO MY ACCOUNT!
I KNOW, RIGHT?
[ Male Announcer ]
INTRODUCINBANKAMERIDEALS,
FREE FOR
ONLINE BANKING CUSTOMERS.
SIGN IN TO YOUR ONLINE BANKING
TO CHOOSE YOUR DEALS TODAY.
Your soups are
so awesomely delicious
my husband and I
can't stop eating 'em!
What's...that...
on your head?
Can curlers!
Tomato basil.
Potato with bacon.
We've got
a lotta empty cans.
[ Male Announcer ] Hear from
our chefs on Facebook
this Friday!
THEN I READ AN ARTICLE
ABOUT A STUDY THAT LOOKED
AT THE LONG TERM HEALTH BENEFITS
OF TAKING MULTIVITAMINS.
THEY USED CENTRUM SILVER
FOR THE STUDY...
SO I GUESS MY WIFE WAS RIGHT.
[ Male Announcer ] CENTRUM.
ALWAYS YOUR MOST COMPLETE.
Meet the 5-passenger
Ford C-MAX Hybrid.
SO I GUESS MY WIFE WAS RIGHT.
When you're carrying
a lot of weight,
C-MAX has a nice little trait,
You see, C-MAX helps
you load your freight,
with its foot-activated
lift gate.
But that's not
all you'll see,
Cause C-MAX also
beats Prius v,
with better MPG.
Say hi to the all-new 47
combined MPG C-MAX Hybrid.
WE BELIEVE THE MORE YOU KNOW,
THE BETTER YOU TRADE.
SO WE HAVE ONGOING WEBINARS
AND INTERACTIVE LEARNING,
PLUS, IN-BRANCH SEMINARS
AT OVER 500 LOCATIONS,
WHERE OUR DEDICATED SUPPORT
TEAMS HELP YOU KNOW MORE
SO YOUR MONEY CAN DO MORE.
[ Rodger ] AT SCOTTRADE,
SEVEN DOLLAR TRADES
ARE JUST THE START.
OUR TEAMS HAVE THE
INFORMATION YOU WANT
WHEN YOU NEED IT.
IT'S ANOTHEREASON
MORE INVESTORS ARE SAYING...
[ All ]
I'M WITH SCOTTRADE.
>> Steve: WELCOME BACK.
YOU'VE SEEN THE VIOLENT VIDEO
THIS WEEK.
FOX NEWS CONTRIBUTOR STEVEN
CROWDER GETTING PUNCHED IN THE
FACE REPEATEDLY BY A PRO UNION
PROTESTER IN MICHIGAN.
WHERE IS THE OUTRAGE FROM THE
MAIN STREAM MEDIA?
JUST TWO YEARS AGO THEY WERE
QUICK TO CHARACTERIZE THE TEA
PARTY RALLIES AS DANGEROUS.
REMEMBER THAT?
SO IS THERE A CLEAR DOUBLE
STANDARD AT WORK?
LOOKS LIKE IT TO US.
HOW DOES IT LOOK TO SENIOR
CONTRIBUTOR AT THE DAILY CALLER,
MATT LIEU I WHO JOINS US LIVE
FROM D.C
GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
>> GOOD MORNING.
>> Steve: WHAT'S INTERESTING IS
THE NIGHT OF THE BIG RALLY,
12,000 PEOPLE OUTSIDE THE STATE
HOUSE THERE IN MICHIGAN, ALL THE
NETWORKS COVERED IT.
YET, WITH THIS INCREDIBLY -- FOR
TV PICTURES, YOU'RE ALWAYS
LOOKING FOR GOOD PICTURES.
TO HAVE AN ASSAULT CAUGHT ON
CAMERA AND FOR THE BIG THREE NOT
TO RUN IT IN THEIR NEWSCAST,
THAT JUST SEEMS LIKE
JOURNALISTIC MALPRACTICE,
DOESN'T IT?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
IT SHOULD BE IRRESISTIBLE TO THE
PRESS TO SHOW PICTURES LIKE
THIS.
IF SOMETHING HAPPENS AND IT'S
NOT CAUGHT ON TAPE, IT'S NOT AS
EFFECTIVE ON TV.
BUT IF YOU GET IT ON VIDEO, IF
YOU GET A PICTURE OF IT, IT
SHOULD HAVE BEEN IRRESISTIBLE.
IT WAS PART OF A LARGER STORY
AND THE PRESS SAID WELL, THE
PROTESTS WERE BOISTEROUS OR THAT
THERE WAS SOME CLASHING.
BUT THEY DIDN'T REALLY SHOW THE
PICTURES.
I THINK WE HEAR A LOT ABOUT
LIBERAL BIAS.
BUT SELECTION BIAS, THE STORIES
YOU DECIDE TO COVER OR NOT COVER
I THINK IS PROBABLY THE MOST
INSIDIOUS FORM OF VIOLENCE.
>> Steve: YEAH.
THE PICTURES WE'RE LOOKING AT
WERE FOR AMERICANS FOR
PROSPERITY, THAT WASN'T JUST
SOMEONE TIPPING IT OVER.
WE HAD SOMEBODY ON THE GRETA
SHOW THAT SAID THE GUYS CAME IN
WITH BOX CUTTERS AND WORKED TO
KNOCK IT DOWN.
CAME DOWN ON MEN, WOMEN AND
CHILDREN, SOME PEOPLE IN
WHEELCHAIRS AND STUFF LIKE THAT.
I MEAN, THAT IS A STORY THAT IS
IRRESISTIBLE, YOU WOULD THINK,
IF PEOPLE WANTED TO TELL A BIG
STORY.
>> IT SHOULD BE.
KEEP IN MIND, AMERICANS FOR
PROSPERITY HAD TO GET PERMITS TO
PUT THIS TENT UP.
THEY ACTUALLY RESERVED THAT
AREA.
THEY HAD ELECTRICITY THERE.
SO THEY WENT THROUGH THE PROPER
CHANNELS TO PROTEST,  WHICH IS
THEIR RIGHT.
AND THE TENT WAS TORN DOWN AND I
HAVE SEEN OTHER VIDEOS, NOT JUST
THE VIDEOS  THAT HAVE SORT OF
GONE VIRAL, BUT OTHER VIDEOS
THAT CLEARLY SHOW THERE WERE
WOMEN AND CHILDREN, ELDERLY
FOLKS IN THERE.
IT'S SORT OF A HORRIFYING THING
AND REALLY HASN'T GOTTEN THE
COVERAGE.
NOW YESTERDAY, AMERICANS FOR
PROSPERITY IN WISCONSIN SAID --
I'M SORRY, MICHIGAN SAID THEY
WERE GOING TO FILE CHARGES OR
THAT THEY HAD.
I GUESS IT'S POSSIBLE THAT IF
THERE IS ANY LEGAL RECOURSE, THE
PRESS MIGHT FINALLY START TO
COVER THIS.
BUT SO FAR, REALLY HASN'T.
>> Steve: YEAH, ALTHOUGH THEY
DIDN'T TELL THE STORY BEFORE.
SO IT'S HARD TO SAY, YOU KNOW, A
COUPLE OF DAYS WHEN WE DIDN'T
TELL BUT THIS STORY, WE THOUGHT
WE'D GIVE YOU AN UPSTATE ON THE
STORY WE DIDN'T TELL YOU.
WHY DO YOU THINK THE MAIN STREAM
IMMEDIATE WHY ARE NOT COVERING
THIS?
-- MEDIA ARE NOT COVERING THIS?
>> IT'S UNCLEAR BECAUSE THE
PICTURES SHOULD MAKE IT
IRRESISTIBLE.
BUT I THINK THE QUESTION THAT A
LOT OF FOLKS BROUGHT UP IS WHAT
WOULD HAPPEN IF IT WERE
REVERSED?
IF IT WERE A TEA PARTY MEMBER.
>> Steve: OH, MY GOODNESS.
>> RIGHT.
REMEMBER A COUPLE YEARS AGO, THE
ALLEGATION THAT A TEA PARTY
PROTESTER USED A RACIAL EPITAPH
RODE THEM FOR DAYS AND THIS WAS
JUST AN ALLEGATION THAT SOMEBODY
SAID SOMETHING.
HERE SOMEBODY HAS PUNCHED
SOMEBODY IN THE FACE.
THIS IS CLEAR, IF THIS WERE
REVERSED, THE MAIN STREAM MEDIA
WOULD BE PLAYING THE VIDEO
INCESSANTLY.
NUMBER TWO, YOU WOULD START TO
SEE CONSERVATIVES COME OUT AND
CONDEMN THE VIOLENCE AND
CRITICIZE A -- THEY WOULD
ACTUALLY TURN ON THE TEA PARTY
GUY, NOT DEFEND HIM.
BUT I THINK THIRDLY, IT WOULD
BECOME PART OF A LARGER
NARRATIVE, RIGHT?
SO IF THE TEA PARTY HAD DONE
THIS, IT WOULD BE, WELL -- MITT
ROMNEY NEEDS TO COMMENT ON THIS.
OR PART OF THE WAR ON WOMEN.
AND THAT CERTAINLY HASN'T
HAPPENED.
THERE ARE THINGS THAT DEMOCRATS
AND I THINK PRESIDENT OBAMA GAVE
A SPEECH.
THERE WAS A DEMOCRATIC
REPRESENTATIVE WHO SAID THERE
WILL BE BLOOD.
JIMMY HOFFA CAUGHT IN A CIVIL
WAR.
ALL THOSE THINGS HAPPENED BEFORE
THE VIOLENCE AND YET, NOBODY IS
REALLY TYING IT INTO THAT LARGER
NARRATIVE.
>> Steve: THAT'S RIGHT.
AND ALSO ON THE LEFT, I KNOW A
NUMBER OF PEOPLE ARE SUGGESTING
STEVEN CROWDER ACTUALLY DESERVED
GETTING THE BEAT DOWN, WHICH IS
CRAZY.
ALL RIGHT.
MATT, THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR
JOINING US TODAY FROM OUR
NATION'S CAPITOL.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Steve: WHAT DO YOU THINK
ABOUT THAT?
THE DOUBLE STANDARD THAT IS
CLEAR?
E-MAIL US.
MEANWHILE, STRAIGHT AHEAD, YOU
THOUGHT THE TALKS ON THE FISCAL
CLIFF WERE BRUTAL?
TAKE A LOOK AT THIS.
LAWMAKERS THROWING FISTS.
WHERE THIS HAPPENED, WE'LL TELL
YOU COMING UP NEXT.
THEN SOMETHING THAT DOESN'T
HAPPEN TOO OFTEN, A MOVIE THAT
THE WHOLE FAMILY COULD SEE
TOGETHER.
YOUR GUIDE TO THE BEST CHRISTMAS
MOVES, NEXT HOUR.
>> GRANDPA TELLS LOTS OF JOKES
THAT YOU WON'T GET.
JUST LAUGH.
>> HELLO, BOYS.
STILL SINGLE?
[ LAUGHTER ]
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with uimited
talk and text.
by HTC for $49.99.
>> Brian: QUICK HEADLINES.
NEW DETAILS ABOUT THE MAN WHO
OPENED FIRE INSIDE A CROWDED
MALL IN OREGON.
JACOB ROBERTS' ROOMMATE SAID HE
HAD A WEIRD LOOK ON HIS FACE
WHEN HE LEFT THE HOUSE THAT DAY.
ROBERTS SHOT AND KILLED TWO
PEOPLE INSIDE THE MALL BEFORE
TURNING THE GUN ON HIMSELF.
THE MALL SET TO REOPEN A LITTLE
BIT LATER THIS MORNING.
>>> COULD JENNY RIVERA HAVE
AVOIDED DEATH?
IT TURNS OUT SHE MADE A LAST
MINUTE DECISION TO TAKE THAT
DEADLY PLANE RIDE.
SHE WAS OFFERED A ROOM FOR THE
NIGHT, BUT TOOK OFF TO HER NEXT
DESTINATION INSTEAD.
>> Gretchen: THAT'S SAD.
TODAY WE WRAP UP OUR PAWS FOR A
CAUSE SERIES.
ALL WEEK WE'VE BEEN TELLING YOU
HOW YOU CAN HELP DOGS IN NEED IN
TIME FOR CHRISTMAS.
HERE WITH US TODAY IS.
>> Brian: DEBORAH ALLRICK, FROM
A MIXED BREED RESCUE, AND
MICHAELA.
WHO ARE YOUR SPECIAL FRIENDS?
>> THIS IS PIXIE RIGHT HERE AND
THIS IS TWIGGY.
>> Brian: THESE PUPPIES?
>> TWINKIE.
>> Gretchen: SHE COULD BE
TWIGGY, YEAH.
>> IS A YORKIE.
SHE'S BLIND.
AND THIS IS PIXIE.
WE REALLY DON'T KNOW WHAT SHE
IS.
>> Steve: THIS IS THE TIME OF
SEASON WHEN I KNOW YOU GUYS TRY
VERY HARD TO MAKE SURE THAT
THESE DOGS DON'T WIND UP STAYING
IN A KENNEL OVER CHRISTMAS.
WHAT'S THE BEST WAY WE CAN ADOPT
THEM OUT AND OTHERS?
THERE ARE THOUSANDS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY.
>> THE FIRST THING IS CHRISTMAS
IS MAYBE NOT THE BEST TIME.
IT'S FUN, THERE IS A LOT GOING
ON.
BUT IF YOU PLAN A LOT OF STUFF
AHEAD OF TIME AND YOU'RE ALL
PREPARED.
BUT I THINK THAT -- IT'S REALLY
HARD.
THE ADOPTION RATES ARE SUPER
DOWN RIGHT NOW.
>> Steve: WHY IS THAT?
>> ECONOMY.
>> Steve: YEAH.
AT THE CAN'T FEED THEMSELVES,
HOW CAN THEY FEED THE DOGS?
>> BUT YOU JUST GO TO THE
SHELTER AND GO TO PETFINDER.COM
AND PICK A BREED.
START LOOK.
>> Gretchen: TWINKIE, HOW DID
SHE BECOME BLIND?
>> SHE WAS BORN THAT WAY.
>> Gretchen: SHE'S SHAKING.
IS SHE COLD OR JUST SCARED?
>> SCARED.
SHE HAD A ROUGH TRIP.
>> Gretchen: OKAY.
>> Brian: I BELIEVE THAT PIXIE
IS A CHIHUAHUA PEKINESE.
COULD THAT BE A GUESS?
>> YEAH.
THIS ONE CAME FROM A BREEDER WHO
CAST HER OFF BECAUSE SHE WAS
BLIND.
>> Steve: SO MANY PEOPLE DO, FOR
ONE REASON OR ANOTHER, THEY
DON'T HAVE A DID YOU GO AND THEY
THINK SOME DAY I'M GOING TO GO
TO THE PET SHOP AND BUY ONE.
THERE ARE MILLIONS OF ANIMALS AT
AMERICA'S SHELTERS THAT ARE SO
EASY AND SO NEEDING A HOME.
>> GRATEFUL.
>> Steve: THEY ARE GRATEFUL.
THEY'RE GREAT DOGS.
>> YOU CAN GET ANY BREED YOU
WANT IN RESCUE.
>> Steve: SOMETIMES IT TAKES A
LITTLE WHILE TO FIND THE ONE YOU
WANT.
>> YES, YOU CAN.
>> Brian: HOW LONG HAVE THEY
BEEN GETTING ALONG LIKE THIS?
>> BLIND?
>> Brian: NO, THEY GET ALONG
WELL.
THEY'RE NOT FIGHTING OR
SCRATCHING.
THESE ARE YOUNG DOGS.
>> THEY'RE REALLY SWEET AND
DON'T HAVE AN ALPHA PERSONALITY
SO THEY'RE TOLERATING.
>> Gretchen: SO THEY DON'T NEED
TO BE IN CHARGE?
>> NO.
>> Gretchen: SO TELL US THE
TYPES OF FAMILIES OR MAYBE
SINGLE PEOPLE WHO WOULD BE A
GOOD FIT FOR THESE DOGS.
>> FOR THIS ONE?
>> Gretchen: YES.
>> I THINK WHEN SHE'S BLIND LIKE
THIS, IT'S A LITTLE HARDER.
SHE'S SO CUTE AND A YORKIE.
IT'S HARD FOR PEOPLE TO
UNDERSTAND THIS SPECIAL NEEDS
DOG.
THEY'RE SPECIAL.
AND A LOT OF PEOPLE WON'T ADOPT
THEM.
BUT SOMEONE LIKE HER, SHE NEEDS
SOMEONE THAT HAS A STABLE
ENVIRONMENT WHERE THINGS DON'T
MOVE AROUND.
>> Brian: THEY DEVELOP THEIR
OTHER SENSES.
>> IF I PUT THIS DOG DOWN, YOU
WOULD NEVER KNOW SHE WAS BLIND.
>> Steve: I KNOW OF PEOPLE WHO
ADOPTED ANIMALS AFTER WATCHING
THIS PROGRAM.
IF PEOPLE WOULD LIKE MORE
INFORMATION ABOUT YOUR PROGRAM,
DO YOU HAVE A WEB SITE?
>> WWW.MIXBREEDRESCUE.COM.
ONE THING I WANT TO SAY IS
BECAUSE THE WORLD IS REALLY IN
THE PUPPY -- INTO PUPPIES, IS TO
THINK ABOUT THESE KIND OF DOGS.
THEY'RE BLIND OR DEAF OR THEY
HAVE A DISEASE.
LOOK AT HER.
SHE'S LOVING.
AND ALSO SENIOR DOGS, BLACK
DOGS, AND BIG DOGS.
>> Brian: THANKS SO MUCH FOR
COMING DOWN AND TELLING A GOOD
STORY.
>> Steve: MERRY CHRISTMAS.
>> MERRY CHRISTMAS.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Gretchen: COMING UP, THE CEO
OF ONE OF THE NATION'S BIGGEST
HEALTH CARE COMPANIES SAYS
OBAMACARE WILL DOUBLE YOUR
PREMIUM AND THAT'S NOT WHAT WE
WERE PROMISED.
REMEMBER YOU CAN KEEP YOUR OWN
HEALTH CARE.
>> Brian: I'M GOING TO.
>> Steve: ARE YOU HEADING FOR
THE HYDRANT?
RIGHT ON THE CORNER.
>> Gretchen: YOU'RE GOING TO THE
HYDRANT?
>> Steve: YEAH.
THEN A MOVIE THE WHOLE FAMILY
CAN SEE TOGETHER.
THE GUIDE COMING UP.
>> GRANDPA TELLS LOTS OF JOKES
THAT YOU WON'T GET.
JUST LAUGH.
>> HELLO BOYS.
STILL SINGLE?
[ LAUGHTER ]
[ Male Announcer ]
COUGHEQUENCE™ #8.
WAKING THE BABY.
[ coughs ]
[ baby crying ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
ROBITUSSIN® LIQUID FORMULA
SOOTHES YOUR THROAT ON CONTACT
AND THE ACTIVE INGREDIENT
RELIEVES YOUR COUGH.
ROBITUSSIN®. DON'T SUFFER
THE COUGHEQUENCES™.
This reduced sodium soup
says it mahelp
lower cholesterol,
how does it work?
You just he to eat it as part
of your heart healthy diet.
Step 1. Eat the soup.
All those
veggies and beans,
that's what may help
lower your cholesterol and --
Well that's easy
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
that's what may help
lower your cholesterol and --
Well that's easy
It's hard to see opportunity
in today's challenging
environment.
Unless you have the right
perspective.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
has the vision
and experience to look beyond
the obvious.
We'll uncover opportunities,
find hidden risk,
and make success a reality.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
NESPRESSO.
WHERE I NEVER HAVE TO COMPROMISE
ON ANYTHING.
♪
WHERE JUST ONE TOUCH
CREATES THE PERFECT COFFEE.
WHERE EVERY CAPPUCCINO AND LATTE
IS ONLY MADE WITH FRESH MILK.
AND WHERE THE STAFF
IS EXCEPTIONALLY FRIENDLY.
♪
NESPRESSO. WHAT ELSE?
>> ACCORDING TO A NEW SURVEY,
70% OF DOG OWNERS WILL BUY THEIR
DOGS A CHRISTMAS GIFT.
BUT VETS SAY THEY CAN'T
COMPREHEND CHRISTMAS, BUT THEY
CAN SENSE THAT WE ARE TOO STUPID
TO KNOW THAT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
THEY WILL HATE THE GIFT.
>> Gretchen: YES, AND I'M ONE OF
THE STUPID ONES WHO JUST WENT
OUT AND BOUGHT MY DOG SOME
CHRISTMAS GIFTS THE OTHER DAY.
THEY'LL GO RIGHT IN THE STOCKING
FOR THE DOG.
AND I BELIEVE THAT MY DOG WILL
KNOW THAT THEY CAME FROM ME.
>> Steve: SURE.
>> Gretchen: AND MY KIDS.
>> Steve: IF YOU LET THE DOG
CHEW UP THE STOCKING, THAT
REALLY IS WHAT DOGS WANT.
>> Gretchen: I HAVE THE KIND OF
DOG THAT CHEWS UP EVERYTHING.
SO I GO FOR THE HARD CORE TOYS.
THEY SAY NO DOG CAN GET THROUGH
THIS, TEN MINUTES LATER,
DESTROYED.
>> Brian: I LET MY DOGS PLAY
WITH OUR HUMMELS, THE RARE
FIGURINES.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Gretchen: OH, MY GOSH.
OKAY.
I HAVEN'T HEARD THAT ONE.
>> Brian: QUICK LOOK AT THE
HEADLINES.
>> Gretchen: OKAY.
ONE OF THE ONLY LIVING MEDAL OF
HONOR RECIPIENTS RECOVERING THIS
MORNING FROM A BRUTAL ATTACK.
DETAILS ON THE FIGHT INVOLVING
DAKOTA MYER UNCLEAR.
WE KNOW AN 18-YEAR-OLD HAS BEEN
CHARGED WITH ASSAULT.
HE WAS AWARDED THE MILITARY'S
HIGHEST HONOR BY PRESIDENT OBAMA
LAST YEAR AND CREDITED WITH
SAVING THE LIVES OF 13 AMERICANS
AND 23 AFGHAN SOLDIERS DAUGHTER
FIRE FIGHT IN 2009.
>> Brian: EVEN THOUGH PRESIDENT
OBAMA PROMISED OBAMACARE WOULD
SAVE YOU MONEY, THE CEO OF THE
NATION'S THIRD BIGGEST HEALTH
CARE COMPANY SAYS IT'S ACTUALLY
GOING TO DOUBLE YOUR PREMIUMS?
THE HEAD OF AETNA SAYS WHEN THE
LAW KICKS IN, SMALL BUSINESSES,
SOME INDIVIDUALS, WILL BE IN FOR
A RATE SHOCK.
HE HAS SHARED HIS CONCERN WITH
THE PRESIDENT AND LAWMAKERS IN
WASHINGTON.
>> Steve: MEANWHILE, FEAST YOUR
EYES ON THIS.
DOES THIS LITTLE GIRL LOOK LIKE
A TERRORIST TO YOU?
>> YOU'RE KIDDING ME.
>> WE'RE GOING TO GET YOU OUT OF
HERE IN A SECOND.
OKAY?
>> Steve: THAT 12-YEAR-OLD GIRL,
WHO IS WHEELCHAIR BOUND, WAS
DETAINED BY THE TSA AT
DALLAS-FORT WORTH AIRPORT.
AGENTS THOUGHT SHE HAD BOMB
RESIDUE ON HER HANDS.
THE GIRL WAS KEPT AWAY FROM HER
MOM WHILE A BOMB SPECIALIST WAS
CALLED IN.
>> IT'S FRIGHTENING AND I GOT
MAD.
>> YOU WOULD THINK THAT THEY
WOULD HAVE CHECKED HER
WHEELCHAIR AND THEY DID NOTHING.
THEN THAT'S WHEN IT JUST SEEMED
TO -- EVERYTHING SEEMED TO
SPIRAL OUT.
>> Steve: AFTER 45 MINUTES, SHE
WAS FREE TO GO.
AGENTS GAVE THE FAMILY NO
EXPLANATION AND NO APOLOGY.
HEART BREAK VIDEO.
>> Gretchen: POLITICIANS
REACHING ACROSS THE AISLE.
OKAY, NOW YOU THINK IS GOING TO
BE GOOD NEWS?
NO, THEY REACH ACROSS THE AISLE
TO THROW PUNCHES.
THEY SAY WE NEED MORE OF THIS IN
AMERICA, BUT THIS IS THE FIRST
SESSION OF UKRAINE'S NEWLY
ELECTED PARLIAMENT.
THE MASSIVE BRAWL STARTED WHEN
LAWMAKERS BURST TO THE FRONT OF
THE CHAMBER AND FOUGHT OVERT
VOTE FOR A NEW PRIME MINISTER
AND SPEAKER.
I DON'T KNOW, JOHN, YOU MAY BE
UP TO SOMETHING.
ALL THESE SECRET MEETINGS
BETWEEN BAINER AND OBAMA,
THEY'VE GONE NOWHERE.
MAYBE IF THEY DUKE IT OUT LIKE
IN A HOCKEY GAME, MAYBE WE GET
SOMETHING SOLVED.
>> Steve: THEY'RE NOT BLUE OR
RED.
THEY'RE BLACK AND BLUE,
ACCORDING TO THOSE PEOPLE.
MEANWHILE, TAKE A LOOK AT THIS,
WERE YOU ABLE TO SEE THIS
MORNING'S METEOR SHOWER?
WE TOLD BUT THIS YESTERDAY.
THIS IS A SHOT OF THE STREAK
SEEN ABOVE THE DESERT IN ISRAEL.
IT TAKES PLACE ONLY A SHORT TIME
AGO.
AS MANY AS 50, AS YOU CAN SEE,
METEORS PER HOUR WERE SAID TO BE
SEEN.
>> Brian: ANYONE HURT?
>> Steve: NO, THEY'RE FINE.
DON'T KNOW ABOUT SPACE, THOUGH.
BUT IN SPACE, NOBODY CAN HEAR
YOU SCREAM.
HERE IS ANOTHER LOOK ABOVE
TYLER, TEXAS.
NASA SAYS THAT THIS YEAR'S SHOW
COULD BE THE BEST AS THE MOON'S
GLARE WON'T INTERFERE WITH
VISIBILITY.
THAT'S IMPORTANT.
MEANWHILE, LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT
WHERE IT IS RAINING.
THEY PROBABLY DIDN'T SEE MUCH IN
TEXAS BECAUSE THE CLOUD COVER.
ALSO BACK THROUGH PORTIONS OF
ARIZONA, NEW MEXICO AND SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA, SHOWERY THERE.
A LITTLE BIT OF SNOW ACTIVITY
EARLY ON THIS FRIDAY UP ALONG
THE EASTERN SHORE OF ERIE AND
ONTARIO.
20S IN THE NORTHERN PLAINS.
MONTANA NOW, THE CHILLY SPOT ON
THIS MAP WITH 13.
WE'VE GOT ABOUT 27 IN RALEIGH
DURHAM AND LATER TODAY, THINGS
WILL WARM UP A LITTLE IN RALEIGH
ALMOST 60.
THE SAME FOR MEMPHIS.
WARM ALONG THE COAST.
50S AND 60S AND 60S THROUGH
PORTION OF TEXAS.
30S IN THE NORTHERN PLAINS AND
PORTIONS OF NEW ENGLAND.
>> Gretchen: BRIAN, MY SON IS
THE SPORTSCASTER AT SCHOOL
TODAY.
SO HE'S PAYING CLOSE ATTENTION
TO SEE WHAT YOU SAY RIGHT NOW.
>> Steve: NO PRESSURE.
>> Brian: I CAN'T WAIT TO SEE
THAT TAPE.
I'M SURE HE'LL DO GREAT.
LET'S TALK ABOUT THURSDAY NIGHT
FOOTBALL.
LET'S START THERE BECAUSE
CINCINNATI AND THE EAGLES LOCKED
IN A GAME THAT CINCINNATI HAD TO
WIN TO KEEP THEIR PLAYOFF HOPES
ALIVE AND THEY DID.
TURNOVERS WERE THE KEY.
PHILADELPHIA GAVE THIS GAME
AWAY.
FIVE TURNOVERS IN ALL.
A MESSY SEASON FOR THEM WHERE
THEY UNDERACHIEVE AND THEY'RE
HAVING A CHANGE IN COACHING.
CINCINNATI WILL FACE PITTSBURGH
NEXT WEEK IN WHAT COULD BE A
PLAYOFF DECIDING GAME.
THE JETS ARE STILL WORKING IN
THE BACKGROUND.
SHOCKING COMMENTS BY ESPN
ANALYSTS ABOUT THE RACE OF AN
NFL ROOKIE SUPERSTAR, RGIII.
ROB PARKER QUESTIONED THE
BLACKNESS OF THE QUARTERBACK
YESTERDAY.
THIS WAS IN RESPONSE TO RG 3
TELLING THE MEDIA THAT HE
REFUSED TO BE DEFINED BY RACE.
HERE IS WHAT PARKER SAID.
>> THIS THING WE ALL KNOW HE HAS
A WHITE FIANCE, THERE WAS A TALK
ABOUT HE'S A REPUBLICAN.
HE'S NOT REALLY, OKAY, BLACK, HE
KIND OF DOES THE THING, BUT HE'S
NOT REALLY DOWN WITH THE CAUSE,
HE'S NOT ONE OF US.
HE'S KIND OF BLACK, BUT HE'S NOT
REALLY LIKE THE GUY YOU REALLY
WANT TO HANG OUT WITH 'CAUSE
HE'S OFF TO SOMETHING.
>> Gretchen: WHAT?
>> Brian: ACTUALLY GOT WORSE
FROM THERE.
GRIFFIN MAY NOT WANT TO BE
DEFINED BY RACE, BUT RELIGION IS
IMPORTANT TO HIM.
LAST MONTH HE TOLD REPORTERS THE
ONLY THING HE FEARS IS GOD.
ESPN SPOKESPERSON SAID THE
COMMENTS WERE APPROPRIATE AND I
THINK HE'S ON SUSPENSION.
I KNOW HIM, HE'S A GREAT GAPE OF
THE I WAS SHOCKED TO SEE THOSE
COMMENTS.
STEVEN H. SMITH SAYS I REALLY
WANT NO PART OF THIS
CONVERSATION.
>> Gretchen: I THINK I'M GOING
TO LEAVE THAT STORY OUT OF MY
SON'S --
>> Brian: IT WILL BE A LITTLE
CONTROVERSIAL.
>> Gretchen: THE JOSH HAMTON
DEAL MAYBE.
>> Brian: FIVE YEARS,
125 MILLION.
>> Gretchen: THANKS.
2012 HAS BEEN AN INCREDIBLE YEAR
AT THE BOX OFFICE.
OUR NEXT GUEST SAYS THE BEST IS
YET DO COME.
SOME OF THE BIGGEST BLOCKBUSTERS
ARE COMING OUT IN TIME FOR
CHRISTMAS.
KEVIN IS THE FOUNDER OF NERD
TEARS.COM.
WHAT DO YOU THINK --
>> FIRST OF ALL, GOOD MORNING.
THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME ON "THE
HOBBIT" IS AN INCREDIBLE FILM
DIRECTED BY PETER JACKSON.
HERE IS THE DEAL, IT'S GOING TO
BE A LITTLE OVERWHELMING FOR
AUDIENCES BECAUSE THERE ARE SIX
DIFFERENT WAYS YOU CAN BUY
TICKETS AND SEE "THE HOBBIT."
2 D, 3 D, 3 D IMAX.
HE SHOT THE FILM IN
REVOLUTIONARY 48 FILMS PER SECT.
TO KEEP THAT LESS GEEKY AS
POSSIBLE, THAT MEANS YOU'RE
GETTING TWICE AS MANY IMAGES ON
SCREEN PER SECOND, SO IT LOOKS
LIKE YOU'RE LOOKING AT MORE REAL
LIFE.
IT LOOKS LIKE YOU'RE LOOKING
INTO A WINDOW OF A REAL LIFE
SET.
IT LOOKS INCREDIBLE.
PETER JACKSON HAS DONE IT AGAIN.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL MARSPIECE.
3 D IS INCREDIBLE.
IF YOU WANT TO BUY THE RIGHT
TICKET, IT WILL BE A DIFFERENCE
OF UP TO $6 IF YOU WANT TO SEE
IT IN 3 DHFR.
IF YOU HAVE A BIG FAMILY, SKIP
IT.
>> Steve: ALL RIGHT.
AND THAT MOVIE OPENS TODAY.
ONE THAT OPENS FOR MOMS AND DADS
ON CHRISTMAS DAY IS "DJANGO
UNCHAINED."
>> YEAH.
THIS IS A QUENTIN TAXPAYER
TINO -- TERRENTINO MOVIE.
NOT A FAMILY MOVIE WHATSOEVER.
HIGH IN THE PROFANITY AND
VIOLENCE ELEMENT.
THE GUY WHO DID "PULP FICTION,"
IT DEALS WITH JAMIE FOX.
HE IS A FORMER SLAVE TURNED
BOUNTY HUNT WHO ARE IS AFTER IT
TO SAVE HIS LIFE.
IT LOOKS INCREDIBLE.
IT OPENS UP ON CHRISTMAS DAY.
IT'S QUENTIN TERRENTINO'S
SEVENTH FILM AND STARS LEONARDO
DiCAPRIO.
FIVE GOLDEN GLOBE NOMINATIONS
YESTERDAY FOR "DJANGO
UNCHAINED."
>> Brian: LET'S TALK ABOUT "LES
MISERABLES."
AM I GOING TO BE PLEASED WITH
THIS?
>> YEAH.
HERE IS THE DEAL, THEY DID A
THING CALLED LIVE SINGING WITH
THIS MOVIE.
IT'S VERY RARE IN MUSICALS
BECAUSE MOST MUSICALS, THEY
RECORD THE MUSIC THREE OR FOUR
MONTHS PRIOR TO GOING ON SET.
SO WHEN THE ACTORS GET THERE,
THEY HAVE TO MIME THE LYRICS.
THIS TIME THEY SING LIVE INTO
THE CAMERA.
THE EMOTION IS HAPPENING RIGHT
THERE.
AND WHAT AT THIS WAS SAT DOWN
WITH HUGH JACKMAN RECENTLY.
HERE IS US, WE LIVE SING OUR
INTERVIEW.
HERE IS HUGH JACKMAN AND MYSELF.
>> TELL ME THE POSITIVES AND
NEGATIVES OF SINGING LIVE ♪
♪ THE NEGATIVES ARE IF YOU DON'T
HAVE A SCORE ♪
♪ LIKE DURING THIS INTERVIEW
♪ WE ARE PRETTY MUCH SINGING THE
SAME NOTES ALL THE TIME ♪
>> Steve: AWESOME.
>> Gretchen: VERY CUTE.
>> WE WERE TOTALLY SINGING.
THEY DO LIVE SING.
IT'S THE MOST BELOVED MUSICAL OF
ALL TIME.
IT'S BEEN SEEN BY OVER
60 MILLION PEOPLE AND OPENS
CHRISTMAS DAY.
>> Gretchen: CHRISTMAS DAY ALSO
OPENS "PARENTAL GUIDANCE."
IT'S A FAMILY MOVIE.
I HAVE A 7 AND 9-YEAR-OLD, CAN I
BRING THEM TO THIS MOVIE?
>> HERE IS THE DEAL WITH THIS
FILM.
THIS IS YOUR FAMILY MOVIE FOR
CHRISTMAS DAY.
IT'S BETTE MIDLER AND BILLY
CRYSTAL, THEY'RE GRANDPARENTS
WATCHING THEIR THREE
GRANDPARENTS.
THERE IS GOING TO BE JOKES  THAT
KIDS ARE GOING TO LOVE.
THERE IS GOING TO BE JOKES THAT
ADULTS LOVE.
IT'S LIKE A PIXAR BALANCE WHERE
KIDS WILL SEE A DIFFERENT MOVIE
AND ADULTS WILL ALSO.
ALL AUDIENCES WILL BE ABLE TO
ENJOY EVERY ELEMENT OF THIS
FILM.
IT'S YOUR FAMILY MOVIE.
>> Steve: THAT'S NICE, IT
OPERATES ON A COUPLE DIFFERENT
LEVELS.
BEFORE YOU GO, THAT BILL MURRAY
MOVIE WHERE HE PLAYS FDR, I'VE
HEARD THAT IT MAY NOT BE UP FOR
AN OSCAR THIS YEAR.
>> NO.
THIS YEAR IS A HUGE, HUGE RACE
FOR THE OSCARS.
YOU HAVE DENZEL WASHINGTON,
DANIEL DAY-LEWIS, A LOT OF
DIFFERENT PEOPLE UP FOR OSCARS.
HE'S NOT GOING TO MAKE THE CUT
'CAUSE THE MOVIE IS NOT THAT
GREAT.
HE IS PHENOMENAL IN THE FILM.
BUT THE MOVIE IS DULL, IT'S A
LITTLE BORING.
I FOUND MYSELF DOZING OFF.
BUT I SAT DOWN WITH BILL MURRAY
BACK IN TORONTO A COUPLE MONTHS
AGO AND FOR SOME REASON, HE
NOTICED THE SUIT THAT I WAS
WEARING HAD A DOT ON IT.
SO HE DECIDE -- HE PROCEEDED TO
GET UP AND CLEAN MY SUIT.
WE HAVE VIDEO HERE.
HE GOT UP AND CLEANED MY SUIT.
I HAVEN'T WASHED THIS SUIT
SINCE.
>> Steve: FROM DAYS WORK AT A
DRY CLEANER.
>> Brian: I LOVED BILL MURRAY IN
"MEAT BALLS".
SEEMED LIKE A VERY SIMILAR ROLE.
>> BRIAN, I WANT TO APOLOGIZE TO
YOU.
HERE COMES THE BOOM DID NOT MAKE
MY TOP TEN THIS YEAR.
>> Gretchen: OH!
>> Brian: FORGET IT!
I'M LEAVING!
>> Gretchen: WAIT A MINUTE.
KEVIN, DID YOU LIKE "FRED
CLAUSE" YEARS AGO?
>> YOU KNOW WHAT?
IT'S A DEKENT MOVIE.
-- DECENT.
WAY BETTER THAN "HERE COMES THE
BOOK."
>> Gretchen: BRIAN IS REDEEMED.
>> Steve: KEVIN, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
AND MERRY CHRISTMAS.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
HAPPY HOLIDAYS.
>> Gretchen: WHAT ARE WE GOING
TO DO?
WE MIGHT END UP DOING THE REST
OF THE SHOW WITHOUT BRIAN.
>> Steve: HE'LL BE BACK.
YOU WATCH.
>> Gretchen: THE BLOGS WILL GO
NUTS WITH BRIAN STORMING OFF.
THEY DON'T UNDERSTAND YOU,
BRIAN.
COMING UP NEXT, 100-YEAR-OLD
FAMILY BUSINESS ABOUT TO BE
EVICTED BY THE FEDS.
WHY THEY'RE BEING SHUT DOWN AND
THE OWNER WHO IS NOT GIVING UP
WITHOUT A FIGHT.
THAT'S NEXT.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAN
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
Your soups are
so awesomely delicious
my husband and I
can't stop eating 'em!
What's...that...
on your head?
Can curlers!
Tomato basil.
Potato with bacon.
We've got
a lotta empty cans.
[ Male Announcer ] Hear from
our chefs on Facebook
this Friday!
>> Gretchen: THAT GRAPHIC SHOULD
BE NOMINATED FOR SOME SORT
AWARD.
THAT'S NICE.
AFTER NEARLY 100 YEARS IN
BUSINESS, THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT
IS FORCING THEM TO SHUT DOWN.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT DRAKE'S BAY
OYSTER FARM IN CALIFORNIA, WAS
RECENTLY INFORMED THAT THEY
WOULD NOT BE ALLOWED TO RENEW
THEIR FEDERAL PARK LEASE.
THE INTERIOR DEPARTMENT PLANS TO
TURN THE LAND INTO A MARINE
WILDERNESS AREA, AND AS A
RESULT, THE OYSTER COMPANY AND
30 EMPLOYEES ARE OUT OF WORK.
KEVIN IS THE OWNER OF DRAKE'S
BAY AND NOW SUING FOR AN
INJUNCTION TO KEEP HIS BUSINESS
OPEN.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU, KEVIN.
>> GOOD MORNING, GRETCHEN.
HOW ARE YOU?
>> Gretchen: DOING JUST FINE.
THANK YOU FOR GETTING UP SO
EARLY.
SO TELL ME WHAT YOU'VE BEEN
DOING FOR ALL THESE YEARS, YOUR
OYSTER FARM.
>> THE OYSTER FARM IS REALLY
KIND OF A MAIN STAY IN OUR
COMMUNITY.
WE PRODUCE ABOUT A THIRD OF THE
OYSTERS GROWN IN THE STATE OF
CALIFORNIA.
WE GET ABOUT 50,000 VISITORS A
YEAR WHO LOVE THIS PLACE, BEEN
HERE FOR OVER EIGHT DECADES AND
THE COMMUNITY AND OUR COUNTY AND
SAN FRANCISCO BAY AREA LOVES USH
WASHINGTON, D.C.
>> Gretchen: SO THE INTERIOR
DEPARTMENT WANTS TO SHUT YOU
DOWN.
WHY?
>> WELL, ACTUALLY A SMALL
HANDFUL OF FOLKS WHO ARE REALLY
WILDERNESS ACTIVISTS WHO CARE
DEEPLY ABOUT GETTING PEOPLE OFF
THE LAND, I THINK IS THE BEST WE
CAN TELL, WANT TO GIVE UP
SOMETHING TO CREATE A HUMANLESS
LANDSCAPE AND IT'S A LITTLE
STRANGE BECAUSE NATIONAL SEA
SHORE WAS CREATED AS A WORK
LANDSCAPE.
THE OYSTER FARM IS COMPLETELY
SURROUNDED BY WORKING RANCHES
AND SO TO REMOVE THE OYSTER FARM
FROM THE MIDDLE OF THE HISTORIC
RANCHING LANDS IS ODD.
>> Gretchen: AREN'T THE OYSTERS
PART OF THE LANDSCAPE?
>> WELL, THEY HAVE BEEN FOR A
VERY LONG TIME.
AS A MATTER OF FACT, THE
NATIONAL ACADEMY OF SCIENCES
SAYS THAT DRAKE'S, WHERE THE
OYSTERS LIVE, IS PROBABLY
HEALTHIER WITH THE OYSTER FARM
BECAUSE OF THE ECO SYSTEM
SERVICES.
IT'S THE REASON THAT WE SEE
OYSTERS BEING PLANTED IN THE
CHESAPEAKE AND SAN FRANCISCO
BAY.
>> Gretchen: RIGHT.
>> AND NOW WE HAVE AN INTERIOR
DEPARTMENT WHO WANTS TO REMOVE
THEM.
>> Gretchen: SO LET ME ASK YOU
THIS, THE BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS -- LET'S FACE IT,
THIS IS NOT A CONSERVATIVE PART
OF THE COUNTRY.
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS, SENATOR
DIANE FEINSTEIN, DEMOCRAT, THEY
LOOKED AT THE CLAIMS AND THEY
ALSO BECAME OUTRAGED AT WHAT'S
HAPPENING TO YOU?
>> AS A MATTER OF FACT, THAT'S
TRUE.
SENATOR FEINSTEIN LOOKED VERY
CAREFULLY AND SHE RECOGNIZED THE
PARK SERVICE ACTUALLY FABRICATED
THE SCIENCE AND MISREPRESENTED
THE SCIENCE, HAD THE NATIONAL
ACADEMY LOOK AT THEIR CLAIMS.
THEY AGREED THAT IT WAS -- THEIR
WORDS WERE, SELECTIVELY
PRESENTED AND OVERINTERPRETED
AND MISREPRESENTED THE CLAIMS.
SO ALL THEIR CLAIMS OF HARM FELL
AWAY, YET SECRETARY SALAZAR
STILL MADE THE DECISION TO
REMOVE THE FARM.
>> Steve: IT'S INTERESTING.
YOU'RE NOW SUING.
PLEASE KEEP US UP TO DATE ON
WHAT HAPPENS TO YOUR OYSTER FARM
IN BEAUTIFUL CALIFORNIA.
THANKS FOR YOUR TIME TODAY.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Gretchen: THE EPA TRYING TO
REGULATE THE RAIN?
AND IT COULD COST PEOPLE THEIR
HOMES.
WE'RE NOT KIDDING.
FIRST ON THIS DAY IN 1964, "COME
SEE ABOUT ME" BY THE SUPREMES
WAS THE NUMBER ONE SONG
♪
[ Male Announcer ] CAMPBELL'S
GREEN BEAN CASSEROLE.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO
ANY TREE  THIS LOT
IS ON ME.
I'M THE MESSENGER,
BY THE WAY.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
JOANNE.
WITH THE HUNDREDS THAT I SAVE
WITH PROGRESSIVE
ON MY CAR INSURANCE,
THIS TREE IS ON ME.
NO WAY.
WAY.
THIS TREE IS ON ME.
REALLY?!
YES.
AAH!
LET ME JUST TRIM IT UP
A ITTLE BIT FOR YOU.
[ buzzing ]
THANK YOU.
SAVING'S GREETINGS.
YOU GUYS ARE GONNA GET THIS TREE
RIGHT HERE?
ARE YOU SURE
THAT'S THE ONE?
I'LL TIE IT TO THE ROOF
FOR YOU.
MAKE SAVINGS
A NEW HOLIDAY TRADITION.
♪
>> Brian: IT'S GOVERNMENT GONE
WILD.
THE STATE OF OF VIRGINIA IS
HEADING TO FEDERAL COURT TO
FIGHT NEW EPA REGULATIONS.
THE AGENCY WANTS VIRGINIA TO
CONTROL AND REGULATE RAIN WATER
ON PRIVATE PROPERTY.
THEY SAY IF THE MOVE GOES
THROUGH, THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE MAY
LOSE THEIR HOMES BECAUSE OF
RAIN.
>> Steve: LIKE IN THAT SONG, WHO
WILL STOP THE RAIN?
THE EPA WANTS TO TRY.
JOINING US IS THE ATTORNEY
GENERAL OF THE GREAT STATE OF
VIRGINIA, KEN CUCCINELLI.
>> GOOD MORNING.
GOOD TO SEE Y'ALL.
>> Steve: I KNOW YOU WERE
ACCUSING THE EPA OF MASSIVE
GOVERNMENT OVERREACH.
WHAT EXACTLY DOES THE EPA WANT
TO DO?
>> WELL, WHAT THEY WANT TO DO IS
THEY WANT TO FORCE FAIRFAX
COUNTY AND THE VIRGINIA
DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION, MY
CLIENT, TO SPEND OVER
$300 MILLION TO CUT THE FLOW OF
RAIN WATER INTO A CREEK BY HALF.
NOT A MUTANT, MIND YOU.
THEY WANT TO TRY AND CUT DOWN ON
THE AMOUNT OF WATER GOING INTO
THE AQUATAIN CREEK.
THE WAY THEY'RE TRYING TO DO IT
IS THE ONLY WAY THEY'VE BEEN
ABLE TO REGULATE POLLUTION.
WELL, WATER ISN'T A POLLUTANT.
THE NAME OF THE LAW IS KIND OF A
GIVE AWAY.
IT'S THE CLEAN WATER ACT AND THE
IDEA IS TO KEEP WATER CLEAN,
FROM POLLUTANTS.
SO THEY'VE GOT IT BACKWARDS
HERE.
>> Brian: WHAT ARE THEY ASKING
PEOPLE WHO LIVE BY THE RIVER TO
DO?
TO TRAP WATER?
>> WELL, THEY'RE AIMING AT THE
LOCAL AND STATE GOVERNMENTS, BUT
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO TAKE
PRIVATE PROPERTY IF WE'RE GOING
TO FULFILL THIS REQUIREMENT.
WHAT THEY ARE TRYING TO GET US
TO STOP, LITERALLY STOP THE FLOW
OF RAIN WATER.
SO THEY OWN ROAD THERE.
THEY DON'T OWN PARKLAND OR
ANYTHING THEY CAN WORK WITH TO
HAVE A POOL TO TRAP WATER.  SO
WE'LL HAVE TO TAKE HOUSES.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO CREATE
POOLS TO HOLD WATER FOR LONGER
PERIODS OF TIME.
AND REALLY ONE SOLUTION IS
TAKING HOMES BY EMINENT DOMAIN,
TEARING THEM DOWN AND PLANTING
GRASS, SO THE WATER SEX IN
INSTEAD OF FLOWS INTO THE CREEK.
THIS IS REALLY JUST LUDICROUS.
THIS IS OVER $300 MILLION OF
PROBABLE COST BETWEEN THESE TWO
AGENCIES FOR ONE CREEK!
>> Steve: IT'S CRAZY.
HERE IS WHAT THE EPA SAYS IN
THEIR MOTION.
EPA'S PROCEEDING IS IN HARMONY
WITH THE BROADER PURPOSE OF THE
CLEAN WATER ACT, CLEAN, THE
OPERATIVE WORD THERE, INCLUDING
CONGRESS' OBJECTIVES OF
PROTECTING THE PHYSICAL AND
BIOLOGICAL INTEGRITY OF WATER
AND REDUCING THE WATER QUALITY
IMPACTS.
THAT SOUNDS LIKE SOMETHING FROM
THE EPA.
THE KEY IS, THIS IS NOTHING NEW.
THIS WAS GOING ON WHERE WATER
WAS RUNNING INTO THAT CREEK WHEN
GEORGE WASHINGTON WAS STILL
RUNNING AROUND THEM PARTS.
>> THE CREEK IS RIGHT NEAR MOUNT
VERNON AND GEORGE WASHINGTON WAS
WRITING IN HIS OWN DIARY ABOUT
HIS INABILITY TO GET ACROSS THIS
CREEK BECAUSE OF HIGH WATER
VOLUME TO GET TO THE HOUSE OF
BURGESSES, WE CALL THE HOUSE
MUCH DELEGATES -- BEFORE WE WERE
A COUNTRY.
SO THIS IS NOT A NEW PROBLEM.
WHAT THE EPA IS DOING, DESPITE
WHAT YOU READ, WE ALL WANT
OBVIOUSLY TO KEEP OUR WATERS
CLEAN, BUT THEY ARE NOT LEGALLY
ALLOWED TO DO IT THIS WAY.
THEY CAN NOT TRY TO FORCE THE
STATE AND LOCAL GOVERNMENTS TO
GET IN THE WAY OF RAIN WATER.
>> Steve: YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY
RIGHT.
IT SOUNDS LIKE A GIGANTIC
OVERREACH BY THE EPA.
WE HOPE YOU'LL KEEP US UPDATED
ON WHAT HAPPENS.
>> Brian: EVERY TIME IT RAINS,
WE'LL THINK OF YOU.
>> GOOD, THANK YOU.
>> Brian: BY THE WAY, 1799,
GEORGE WASHINGTON DIED ON THIS
VERY DAY.
>> Steve: THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
MEANWHILE, DO YOUR HOLIDAY
PICTURES ALL TURN OUT DARK OR
BLURRY?
DON'T GO TO A PROFESSIONAL.
WE'VE GOT FIXES FOR YOU FREE IN
THE NEXT HOUR.
>> Brian: WORK OUT WHILE YOU
WORK?
THAT'S WHAT GERALDO IS DOING
RIGHT NOW.
YES.
HOW YOU CAN GET A BURN AT THE
OFFICE AND NOT GET BURNED AT TH
OFFICE
♪Make just one someone happy
♪And you will be happy too.
But when I was in an accident...
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
So I never missed a beat.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.
[ Male Announcer ] HOW COULD
SWITCHGRASS IN ARGENTINA,
CHANGE ENGINEERING IN DUBAI,
ALUMINUM PRODUCTION
IN SOUTH AFRICA,
AND THE AEROSPACE INDUSTRY
IN THE U.S.?
AT T. ROWE PRICE,
WE UNDERSTAND THE CONNECTIONS
OF A COMPLEX, GLOBAL ECONOMY.
IT'S JUST ONE REASON
OVER 75% OF OUR MUTUAL FUNDS
BEAT THEIR 10-YEAR
LIPPER AVERAGE.
T. ROWE PRICE.
INVEST WITH CONFIDENCE.
REQUEST A PROSPECTUS
OR SUMMARY PROSPECTUS
WITH INVESTMENT INFORMATION,
RISKS, FEES AND EXPENSES
TO READ AND CONSIDER CAREFULLY
BEFORE INVESTING.
Neural speeds
increasing to 4G LTE.
Brain upgrading to a quad-core
processor.
Predictive intelligence
with Google Now complete.
Introducing DROID DNA by HTC.
It's not an upgrade
to your phone.
It's an upgrade to yourself.
. .
BECAUSE Enbrel, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS,
SOMETIMES FATAL EVENTS
INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS,
LYMPHOMA, OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING Enbrel,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START Enbrel IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILEN Enbrel, YOU
EXPERICE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING, OR PALENESS.
[ Phil ]
GET BACK TO THE THINGS
THAT MATTER MOST.
ASK YOUR RHEUMATOLOGIST
IF Enbrel IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
[ Doctor ]
Enbrel, THE NUMBER ONE
BIOLOG MEDICINE
PRESCRIBED BY RHEUMATOLOGISTS.
>> Gretchen: GOOD MORNING,
EVERYBODY.
TODAY IS FRIDAY, TGIF,
DECEMBER 14.
I'M GRETCHEN CARLSON.
I FEEL A LOT BETTER BECAUSE
GERALDO WILL BE JOINING US.
>> YOU DOLL!
>> Gretchen: YOU CAN COUNT HER
OUT.
SUSAN RICE TELLING THE PRESIDENT
TO WITHDRAW HER NAME NOW FOR
CONSIDERATION FOR SECRETARY OF
STATE.
WHY NOW AFTER SHE HELD TWO
MEETINGS WITH GOP SENATORS?
IS IT BECAUSE THERE IS ANOTHER
REPORT POSSIBLY ABOUT TO COME
OUT?
>> Brian: DON'T ANSWER THAT,
GERALDO.
>> Steve: YEAH.
HE FACED DOWN INSURGENTS BURKS
HIS TREATMENT INSIDE A MEXICAN
PRISON HAS THE FAMILY OF THIS
FORMER MARINE TERRIFIED FOR HIS
LIFE.
GERALDO, AS YOU'VE JUST HEARD,
IS HERE WITH BRAND-NEW DETAILS.
>> Brian: AND NO DIVINE
INTERVENTION HERE.
A JESUS LOOK ALIKE KICKED OUT OF
A SPORTS STADIUM.
>> Steve: WHY?
>> Brian: THERE IS A LOT TO
DISCUSS THERE.
"FOX & FRIENDS" STARTS NOW.
♪ Y'ALL READY FOR THIS
♪ .
>> Steve: HOW OFTEN HAVE YOU
SAID TO YOURSELF, I'M SITTING AT
THIS DESK ALL DAY, I WISH I
COULD GET SOME EXERCISE.
NOW YOU CAN WITH THE FIT DESK.
IT'S A DESK THAT DOUBLES AS A
WORKOUT BIKE.
AS YOU CAN SEE, WE'RE WORKING
OUR CREW IN THE NEWS ROOM,
SCREEN RIGHT.
AND SALLY IN THE GREEN ROOM,
SCREEN LEFT.
AS THEY CONTINUE TO WORK ON THIS
HERE TELECAST.
>> Brian: I ALWAYS, ALWAYS READ
WHETHER IT'S THE ELLIPTICAL OR
ON THE STATIONARY BIKE.
THIS IS GENIUS.
>> Steve: IT IS VERY, VERY
SMART.
THE PRICE IS SURPRISING.
YOU'RE LOOK FOR A SPECIAL
CHRISTMAS GIFT FOR SOMEBODY FOR
THIS CHRISTMAS SEASON, THIS
WOULD BE GOOD.
>> Gretchen: YOU KNOW WHAT I
LOVE ABOUT IT?
IT'S THE CAPITALISM AND EDGE
ENTWHISTLEISM AT ITS BEST.
THE GUYS WHO CAME UP WITH THIS
JUST CAME UP WITH IT A COUPLE
YEARS AGO.
THEY DIDN'T REALLY MAKE A BUCK.
NOW YEAH.
THEY'VE BEEN SUCCESSFUL 'CAUSE
IT WORKS.
>> Steve: YOU KNOW WHAT?
WE NEED TO HAVE THE CREW GET NOT
GUILTY SHAPE BECAUSE LATER TODAY
WILL BE THE "FOX & FRIENDS"
ANNUAL CHRISTMAS PARTY AND THIS
TIME WE'RE DOING -- IT'S NOT
GOING TO BE THAT SILLY BUCKING
BULL AT JOHNNY UTAH LIKE LAST
TIME.
INSTEAD, WE'RE GOING TO GO
BOWLING.
>> Brian: NUMBER ONE, HOW GREAT
IS IT THAT WE ASKED TWO STAFFERS
TO HELP US OUT, BUT WE WOULD NOT
GIVE THEM OFF FROM THEIR JOB.
THEY WERE BOTH STILL DOING THEIR
JOBS WHILE HELPING US OUT.
>> Gretchen: THAT'S THE WHOLE
POINT OF THE BIKE!
>> Brian: I THINK WE COULD HAVE
GIVEN THEM 90 SECONDS OFF.
>> Gretchen: WE'RE GOING TO GIVE
THEM -- IN 6 1/2 HOURS, WE'RE
GOING TO GIVE THEM FREE DRINKS.
>> Brian: WE'LL SEE.
I WILL SAY, THIS I HAVE A
CONFESSION.
LAST YEAR WAS THE BUCKING BULL.
>> Gretchen: I GOT HURT.
>> Brian: I WAS ON A LONG TIME.
>> Steve: YES, YOU WERE.
>> Brian: THERE WAS A REASON
WHY.
>> Gretchen: OH, GOSH.
>> Brian: GAVE THE GUY 20 BUCKS.
>> Gretchen: YOU DID NOT!
>> Brian: I GAVE THE GUY 20
BUCKS TO MAKE ME LOOK REALLY
GOOD.
>> Steve: NOW YOU KNOW THE REST
OF THE STORY.
>> Brian: RIGHT.
>> Gretchen: I GOT AN INJURED
HAND ON THAT DAMN BULL NOW I'M
FINDING OUT THERE WAS A LOT OF
BULL ON THIS!
YOU GAVE HIM 20 BUCKS?
>> Brian: YEAH, I CHEATED.
IT WAS A GREAT YEAR.
>> Gretchen: IT'S NOT THE FIRST
TIME BECAUSE YOU CHEAT EVERY
TIME WE HAVE A RACE OUTSIDE IN
THE NASCAR.
>> Brian: ONLY IF I'M LOSING.
>> Steve: 'TIS THE SEASON FOR
HEADLINES.
>> Gretchen: HE FINALLY WENT TO
CONFESSION.
FOX NEWS ALERT.
A LITTLE SHAKING GOING ON OUT IN
CALIFORNIA.
TWO LARGE BACK TO BACK
EARTHQUAKES SHAKING THE
CALIFORNIA COAST THIS MORNING
THE 6.4 MAGNITUDE QUAKE ROCKED
THE SOUTHWEST COAST NEAR BAHA
ABOUT AN HOUR AGO.
MOMENTS LATER, A 6.1 MAGNITUDE
QUAKE STRUCK, FELT IN SAN DIEGO
AND LOS ANGELES.
SO FAR, NO REPORTS OF ANY DAMAGE
OR INJURY.
>>> THE UNITED STATES RAMPING UP
ITS INVOLVEMENT IN THE CRISIS
NOW IN SYRIA.
NEW VIDEO INTO OUR NEWS ROOM OF
LEON PANETTA SPEAKING HOUSE
AFTER HE SIGNED AN AGREEMENT TO
SEND TWO PATRIOT MISSILES AND
400 TROOPS INTO THE MIDDLE
EASTERN NATION.
THAT'S TO HELP BEEF UP THE
THREAT AGAINST POTENTIAL SYRIAN
ATTACKS.
THE MISSILES WILL BE UNDER NATO
CONTROL.
>>> THE DEADLINE FOR STATES TO
DECIDE IF THEY'RE GOING TO SET
UP THEIR OWN INSURANCE
EXCHANGES.
24 STATES OPTED OUT.
THAT'S LOT.
19, INCLUDING THE DISTRICT OF
COLUMBIA, WILL HAVE THE
STATE-RUN EXCHANGES.
SIX STATES PLAN ON SPLITTING THE
RESPONSIBILITY WITH THE FEDS.
UTAH AND FLORIDA ARE THE ONLY
TWO STATES HAVEN'T MADE A
DECISION YET.
>>> THE TALIBAN'S GOAL IS KILL
AMERICANS.
AMERICAN TROOPS ARE BEING TOLD
NOW TO PLAY NICEY NICE WITH
THEM.
REPORTS THAT A NEW DRAFT OF THE
ARMY HANDBOOK SAYS OUR TROOPS
IGNORANCE OF CULTURE HAVE LED TO
ATTACKS.
TROOPS SHOULD NOT SPEAK OUT
AGAINST THE TALIBAN OR DEFENDS
WOMEN'S RIGHTS.
>> Brian: SEE, THAT'S OUR FAULT.
WE WERE SPEAKING OUT AGAINST OUR
ENEMY.
WHAT WERE WE THINKING.
>> Gretchen: THE MESSAGE ISN'T
SITTING WELL WITH AFGHANISTAN'S
TOP COMMANDER, GENERAL JOHN
ALLEN RIGHT THERE.
HE REFUSES TO ENDORSE THE BOOK.
>> Brian: THANK YOU.
>> Gretchen: AT LEAST 73 PEOPLE
HAVE DIED IN INSIDER ATTACKS
THIS YEAR.
>> Brian: 'CAUSE WE'RE IGNORANT
OF THE CULTURE?
THEY'VE INFILTRATED THE ARMY!
>> THEY DID BURN THE KORANS.
>> Brian: NOT EVERY DAY.
>> THERE ARE SOME CULTURAL THATY
IN VIOLENCE.
THE BOOK OVERDOES IT.
>> Brian: SOME CULTURES GO TO
THE BATHROOM WITH THE DOOR OPEN.
DOESN'T MEAN I WANT TO SHOOT
THEM.
>> WE DO THAT IN MY HOUSE.
>> Steve: LET'S TALK A LITTLE
BIT ABOUT --
>> SEEMED LIKE AN APPROPRIATE AD
LIB.
>> Brian: THE RIVERA MANSION,
THEY'RE ALL OPENING UP!
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Steve: LOOKS LIKE SUSAN
RICE --
>> YOU'RE VISION IN WHITE.
>> Gretchen: THANK YOU.
>> Brian: WE GOT TO GET YOU SOME
RITALIN BECAUSE YOU CAN NOT STAY
ON A TOPIC.
>> MY WIFE SAYS THAT.
>> Steve: SUSAN RICE TOOK HER
NAME OUT OF CONTENTION TO BE THE
SECRETARY OF STATE.
SHE WRITES IN THE OP ED PAGES OF
THE "WASHINGTON POST" TODAY
ESSENTIALLY THAT THE
ADMINISTRATION CAN'T AFFORD A
FIGHT OVER HER AND THEY WERE
GETTING ONE BECAUSE SHE SIMPLY
SAID CRAZY STUFF ON TV REGARDING
THE BENGHAZI ATTACKS.
>> IT BECAME CLEAR TO ME, AND
THAT'S WHY I SAT ON THIS COUCH A
COUPLE WEEKS AGO, THAT HER SHIP
SAILED.
A COUPLE THINGS HAPPENED, NUMBER
ONE, THERE WAS AN ATTACK CULTURE
IN WASHINGTON WHEN IT BECOMES
CLEAR THAT THE ENTIRE
ESTABLISHMENT IS GOING AGAINST
YOU.
LOOK WHAT HAPPENED TO MY OLD
PAL, THE FORMER ATTORNEY
GENERAL, ALBERTO GONZALEZ.
I HAD TO MEET HIM SECRETLY.
IT BECAME CLEAR THAT EVERYBODY
WAS PILING ON.
IN THE CASE OF AMBASSADOR RICE
WHEN THEY STARTED DIGGING UP
WHAT HAPPENED IN AFRICA IN 1998
IN THE TANZANIA AND KENYA EMBASE
BOMBINGS WHEN SHE WAS A
RELATIVELY LOW LEVEL PERSON, SHE
GOT PILED ON FOR THAT.
WHEN THEY STARTED ANDING THE
FINANCES OF AMBASSADOR RICE AND
HER HUSBAND WHO ARE QUITE
WEALTHY AND STARTED POURING INTO
EVERY DETAIL AND SHE WAS NOT
BEING DEFENDED BY THE
ADMINISTRATION.
I MEAN, THE PRESIDENT WAS MAKING
ALL THE RIGHT SOUNDS, IF YOU
WANT TO PICK ON ANYONE, PICK ON
ME, THUMPING HIS CHEST AND ALT
REST.
BUT THE FACT IS, SHE HAD NO
GROUP APPOINTED BY THE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION TO DEFEND HER
AGAINST THESE ATTACKS.
BUT THE TWO NORTHEASTERN NOD
RATE REPUBLICANS, SUSAN COLLINS
AND KELLY AYOTTE, JOINED THE
ANGRY WHITE MEN, YOU KNOW,
GRAHAM AND McCAIN, AND THEN IT
COULDN'T BE A MALE-FEMALE ISSUE
AGAINST THIS POOR BELEAGUERED
BLACK WOMAN --
>> Brian: YOU DON'T BELIEVE
THAT.
>> Gretchen: ANGRY OLD WHITE
MEN?
>> I AM SPEAKING EXPANSESIVELY
AND METAPHORLY AND FOR EFFECT
HERE.
BUT IT BECAME CLEAR SHE COULDN'T
BE THE BELEAGUERED DAMSEL IN
DISTRESS.
THE POOR BLACK EMBATTLED
AMBASSADOR.
IT BECAME CLEAR THAT SHE WAS THE
MINIMUM PRICE.
I HAVE TO SAY ONE MORE SENTENCE.
SHE WAS THE MINIMUM PRICE TO PAY
FOR THE ADMINISTRATION'S
DISASSEMBLING ON THE FACTS AND
CIRCUMSTANCES OF THE BENGHAZI
ATTACK.
SHE WAS GOING TO BE THE MINIMUM
PRICE THAT THE DEMOCRATS THAT
THE OBAMA ADMINISTRATION HAD TO
PAY FOR THAT CLEAR OFFENSE JUST
AS I BELIEVE THE TAX HIKE ON THE
2% IS THE MINIMUM PRICE THE
REPUBLICANS HAVE TO PAY FOR
LOSING THE ELECTION.
IN WASHINGTON YOU MAKE MINIMUM
PRICES.
SHE'S THE SACRIFICIAL LAMB.
>> Gretchen: I TOTALLY AGREE
WITH YOU, IT WAS THE SENATOR
FROM MAINE, THAT THAT WAS --
COLLINS, THAT WAS IT, BECAUSE
SHE IS THE MODERATE.
IF YOU COULDN'T GET THE
MODERATES ON BOARD.
BUT HERE IS MY QUESTION FOR YOU,
DOES THIS MEAN THAT BENGHAZI
GOES AWAY NOW?
BECAUSE NOW THERE IS ALL THIS
TALK THAT HILLARY CLINTON, SHE
WAS GOING TO TESTIFY
DECEMBER 20, NOW SHE MAY NOT
BECAUSE THERE MAY BE THIS
BOMBSHELL REPORT THAT'S COMING
OUT AND MAYBE HILLARY CLINTON
WANTS TO RUN FOR PRESIDENT.
>> THAT'S A LOT THERE.
REMEMBER MUNICH, 1972, THE
ISRAELI ATHLETES ARE MASSACRED
BY THE PALESTINIAN RADICALS IN
THE OLYMPIC GAMES.
ALL RIGHT.
THEN YOU HAVE FOR THE NEXT
DECADE THE ISRAELIS HUNTING DOWN
THE PERPETRATORS AND KILLING THE
PEOPLE WHO PERPETRATED THE MASS
MURDER OF THE ISRAELI ATHLETES.
THAT'S THE ARMED FORCES
APPROACH, OR THE SENDING SEAL
TEAM 6 AGAINST OSAMA BIN LADEN.
THAT'S THE MILITARY APPROACH.
WHAT'S HAPPENING IN BENGHAZI IS
PRETTY CLEAR TO ME.
IT'S A LAW ENFORCEMENT APPROACH.
WE BUSTED THEM AT THE AIRPORT IN
TURKEY.
IN CAIRO THE COPS THERE
APPREHENDED ONE OF THE ALLEGED
MASTERMINDS OF THE BENGHAZI
ATTACKS.
IT'S CLEAR THERE WILL BE A LAW
ENFORCEMENT APPROACH TO CATCHING
THE PERPETRATORS OF THE BENGHAZI
ATTACKS.
NOT A MILITARY APPROACH.
NOW, I BELIEVE IN TERMS OF THE
HILLARY CLINTON TESTIMONY, THEY
CAN NOW USE THAT SECRETIVE,
UNDERCOVER, LAW ENFORCEMENT
APPROACH AS THE REASON THEY DO
NOT PUBLICLY DISCLOSE WHAT
THEY'RE DOING TO APPREHEND THE
PERPETRATORS -- BUT ALSO MAY BE
TRUE.
>> Brian: THE LAW ENFORCEMENT
APPROACH HAS FALLEN VERY SHORT.
>> WE HAVE A HALF DOZEN IN
CUSTODY.
>> WE HAD A SENATOR WHO HAD TO
GET THE F.B.I. IN TO QUESTION
THOSE CAPTURED WOULD BE KILL
INCREASE TUNISIA.
THERE HAS BEEN NO PURSUIT BY OUR
GOVERNMENT TO QUESTION THESE
GUYS.
>> THE ONE THING WE CAN'T DO,
IT'S CLEAR TO EVERYBODY, IS HAVE
A DRONE GO OVER THE MILITIA
HEADQUARTERS IN BENGHAZI AND
BOMB THEM BECAUSE IT'S TOO SMALL
THERE.
YOU DON'T KNOW, YOU KNOW, THIS
GUY FROM -- THE PERPETRATOR FROM
HIS COUSIN.
IT'S A VERY DIFFICULT SITUATION.
I THINK THAT PRECISE SURGICAL
STUFF IS MAYBE THE WAY TO DO IT.
>> Gretchen: WE HAVE TO GET ON
TO ANOTHER STATE DEPARTMENT
ISSUE, THE FORMER MARINE SERVED
IN IRAQ AND AFGHANISTAN, HE'S
GOING TO COSTA RICA.
HE STOPS IN MEXICO, REGISTERS
HIS GUN BEFORE HE GOES ACROSS
THE BORDER.
NOW HE'S BEEN IN JAIL SINCE
AUGUST.
HE'S CHAINED TO A BED.
SHOULD THE STATE DEPARTMENT BE
WORKING HARDER TO GET HIM HOME?
>> FIRST OF ALL, UNIQUELY I
COVERED MEXICAN PRISONS.
I'VE BEEN INSIDE THE MOST
NOTORIOUS.
I'VE NEVER SEEN AN INMATE CHAIN
TO DO A BED.
I'M NOT SAYING THAT THE
CONGRESSWOMAN IS NOT BEING, YOU
KNOW, ACCURATE HERE.
I'M JUST SAYING IN MY
EXPERIENCE, HAVE NEVER SEEN IT.
REMEMBER ALSO THAT THE MEXICANS
ARE EXTREMELY TICKED OFF ABOUT
FAST AND FURIOUS AND ALL THE
GUNS WE POURED INTO THAT
COUNTRY.
THEY'RE --
>> Steve: BUT TO CHAIN HIM TO A
BED?
>> WE DON'T KNOW THAT'S THAT
TRUE.
SECONDLY, REMEMBER THEY ARE
VERY, VERY SENSITIVE ABOUT THEIR
OWN SOVEREIGNTY AND THE FACT
THAT AMERICAN GUNS HAVE BEEN
POURING INTO THE COUNTRY.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THAT DOESN'T IN ANY WAY SAY THIS
MAN SHOULD BE BEHIND BARS
BECAUSE I THINK IT IS AN
ATROCITY.
I DON'T KNOW WHY OUR CUSTOMS AND
BORDER PROTECTION PEOPLE DIDN'T
WARN HIM.
HE'S BRINGING A SHOTGUN INTO
MEXICO, SAY, HEY, DUDE, THEY'RE
GOING TO BUST YOU 100 FEET FROM
HERE!
>> Gretchen: WE WERE THE FIRST
ONES TO BREAK THIS STORY.
WE INTERVIEWED THE MOM A COUPLE
DAYS AGO.
SHE DECIDED TO GO PUBLIC BECAUSE
SHE'S BEEN SPEAK TO GO HER SON
IN PRISON AND HE'S TOLD HER HE'S
CHAINED TO A BED.
AND HE'S FEARING NOW FOR HIS
LIFE.
THIS TAKES IMMENSE COURAGE FOR
THE FAMILY TO COME FORWARD AND
THEY NEED THE HELP FROM OUR
COUNTRY TO BRING HIM HOME.
>> WELL, I THINK WE CAN ALL
SUGGEST TO THE MEXICANS NO HARM,
NO FOUL.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM HERE?
HE APOLOGIZES.
HE WAS BRINGING A SHOTGUN, AN
OLD SHOTGUN ON A SURFING
EXPEDITION.
HOWEVER, AND HE HAD POST VIETNAM
STRESS, POST IRAQ, AFGHANISTAN
STRESS AND ALL THAT.
I THINK THEY CAN CUT US SOME
SLACK AND I THINK THE NOISE AND
THE FURY ON THIS SIDE WILL BE
HELPFUL.
>> Brian: I LOOK FORWARD TO YOU
COVERING THIS SHOW.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> Brian: WHEN ARE YOU GOING TO
AIR IT?
>> THE WEEKEND, ON SATURDAY
NIGHT.
BRIGHT FUTURE.
THE SENATE.
>> Brian: IT'S A LOT OF MONEY.
A MILLION DOLLARS.
>> YOU THINK I COULD GO?
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> I'LL FLEE A HEARTBEAT.
>> Brian: THAT IS NOT TRUE.
>> Gretchen: SORRY, KIDS.
NO CHRISTMAS CONCERT THIS YEAR.
HOW ABOUT AN ANTI-BULLYING
SPEECH INSTEAD?
THE STORY COMING UP.
♪
>> Brian: THEN DID YOU HEAR THE
NEWS?
THE FEDS FINALLY HAS PLAN TO FIX
OUR ECONOMY.
PRINT MORE MONEY.
WHAT DO YOU THINK ABOUT THAT?
MINE IS WORTH LESS AND LESS.
I'M DOING MY OWN SLEEP STUDY.
ADVIL PM® OR TYLENOL PM.
THE ADVIL PM® GUY
IS SPENDING LESS TIME
LYING AWAKE
WITH ANNOYING ACHES AND PAINS
AND MORE TIME ASLEEP.
ADVIL PM®. THE DIFFERENCE
IS A BETTER NIGHT'S SLEEP.
I just finished a bowl of your
new Light Chicken Pot Pie Soup
and it's so rich
and creamy...
is it really 100 calories?
Let me put you on webcan...
...lean roasted chicken...
and a creamy broth
Mmm
I can still see you.
[ Male announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
AND WITH MY BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CREDIT CARD,
I LOVE 'EM EVEN MORE.
I EARN 1% CASH BACK EVERYWHERE,
EVERTIME.
2% ON GROCERIES.
3% ON GAS.
AUTOMATICALLY.
NO HOOPS TO JUMP THROUGH.
THAT'S 1% BACK ON...
[ toy robot sounds ]
2% ON PUMPN PIE.
AND APPLE.
3% BACK ON 4 TRIPS
TO THE AIRPORT.
IT'S AS EASY AS..
-[ man ] 1...
-[ woman ] 2...
[ woman ] 3.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CARD.
APPLY ONLINE OR AT
A BANK OF AMERICA NEAR YOU.
>> Gretchen: FEDERAL RESERVE
CHAIR BEN BERNANKE SAYS EASY
MONEY IS GOOD FOR THE ECONOMY.
SO LET'S KEEP IT COMING.
KEEP PRINTING IT.
BUT WILL PUSHING INTEREST RATES
AS LOW AS THEY CAN GO EVENTUALLY
BACKFIRE?
>> Brian: JAMES FREEMAN IS
ASSISTANT EDITORIAL EDITOR FOR
THE "WALL STREET JOURNAL."
JAMES, HE IS GOING TO BUY
$85 BILLION WORTH OF DEBT EVERY
MONTH UNTIL OUR UNEMPLOYMENT
GETS DOWN TO 6.5%.
GOOD OR BAD?
>> I THINK WE'VE BEEN TRYING
THIS FOR FIVE YEARS BASICALLY,
PRINTING MONEY TO SEE IF THAT'S
HOW YOU GROW AN ECONOMY.
SORT OF LIKE THE OLD "SATURDAY
NIGHT LIVE" SKIT WITH
CHRISTOPHER WALKEN.
HE ONLY KNOWS HOW TO SAY IS MORE
COW BELL.
ALL BEN BERNANKE SEEMS TO KNOW
HOW TO RESPOND TO THE ECONOMY IS
MORE MONEY CREATION.
I THINK WHAT WE'VE LEARNED THESE
FIVE YEARS, WE STILL HAVE SLOW
GROWTH, HIGH UNEMPLOYMENT IS YOU
CAN'T PRINT MONEY.
YOU CAN'T PRINT YOUR WAY OUT OF
A BAD ECONOMY.
YOU NEED TO ACTUALLY WORRY ABOUT
GROWTH AND HOW YOU GET PEOPLE TO
WORK AND INVEST.
>> Gretchen: SO IF YOU WERE
ADVISING BEN BERNANKE, WHAT
WOULD YOU TELL HIM TO DO
INSTEAD?
>> JUST FOCUS ON STABLE PRICES.
DON'T TRY TO PRINT MONEY AS A
WAY TO OFFSET ALL THE OTHER
MISTAKES THEY'RE MAKING IN
WASHINGTON.
YOU JUST FOCUS ON A STABLE
DOLLAR, PEOPLE CAN DEPEND ON IT,
AND THEN WHAT YOU DO IS YOU
FORCE THE GOVERNMENT, THE REST
OF THE GOVERNMENT, TO FINALLY
GET SPENDING IN CHECK, GET A TAX
AND REGULATORY POLICY THAT
ALLOWS BUSINESSES TO GROW.
>> Brian: BY HIM PRINTING MONEY
YOU JUST TOLD US, HE'S KEEPING
THE PRESSURE OFF THE PRESIDENT
TO CUT SPENDING.
>> YEAH.
BECAUSE RIGHT NOW, THE
GOVERNMENT IS ABLE TO FINANCE
THIS MASSIVE DEBT AT ABOUT 2% A
YEAR.
THE PRESSURE IS NOT ON THEM.
IF INTEREST RATES WENT DO SORT
OF NORMAL, REASONABLE LEVELS,
THE GOVERNMENT ALL OF A SUDDEN,
TO FINANCE THE DEBT, WOULD BE
SPENDING WHAT WE SPEND ON
MEDICARE EVERY YEAR.
IT WOULD FORCE RESPONSIBILITY.
RIGHT NOW ALL OF THIS CREDIT
BASICALLY TO THE GOVERNMENT
ALLOWS THEM TO RUN HUGE DEBT.
>> Gretchen: WE LOOK AT WHAT IS
HAPPENING IN GREECE WHERE THEY
CAN NOT PRINT THEIR OWN MONEY
AND THEY HAVE A MASSIVE SPENDING
PROBLEM.
YOU HAVE RIOTING IN THE STREET.
SO IN A WAY, IN AMERICA, SINCE
YOU CAN PRINT THE MONEY, IT'S
JUST KICKING THE CAN DOWN THE
ROAD, RIGHT?
>> I THINK PEOPLE REALIZE
INTUITIVELY, THIS CAN'T WORK
FOREVER.
THE BIGGEST BUYER NOW OF OUR
LONG-TERM BONDS IS THE FEDERAL
RESERVE.
IN OTHER WORDS, THE GOVERNMENT
ITSELF IS PRINTING MONEY TO LOAN
TO THE GOVERNMENT.
THIS CAN ONLY WORK FOR SOME
PERIOD OF TIME BEFORE THE REST
OF THE WORLD SAYS, WE NO LONGER
TRUST THE U.S. DOLLAR.
WE DON'T GIVE IT THE CREDIBILITY
WE USED TO.
>> Brian: PEOPLE OUTSIDE OUR
WINDOWS DON'T TRUST THE U.S.
DOLLAR.
THAT'S THE SCARY PART.
>> PEOPLE HAVE BEEN EXCITED
ABOUT THE RISE IN HOME PRICES.
IT'S JUST THE LONG-TERM, THIS IS
NOT HOW YOU GROW AN ECONOMY.
THIS IS NOT HOW YOU THRIVE.
>> Gretchen: ALL RIGHT.
YOU HEARD IT FROM JAMES FREEMAN,
WITH THE "WALL STREET JOURNAL."
THANKS.
>> THANKS.
>> Brian: 19 MINUTES AFTER THE
HOUR.
>> Gretchen: NO LOVE FOR JESUS?
A JESUS LOOK ALIKE TOSSED RIGHT
OUT OF A SPORTS STADIUM AND WAIT
UNTIL YOU HEAR WHY.
>> Brian: DO YOUR CHRISTMAS
PHOTOS ALWAYS TURN OUT LIKE
THIS?
THERE ARE SIMPLE THINGS YOU CAN
DO TO MAKE SURE YOUR PHOTOS ARE
PICTURE PERFECT.
WE'LL SHARE THE SECRETS, IF YOU
PROMISE TO KEEP IT A SECRET.
YEARS AGO, MY DOCTOR TOLD ME
TO TAKE A CENTRUM SILVER
MULTIVITAMIN EVERY DAY.
I TOLD HIM, SURE.
CAN'T HURT, RIGHT?
THEN I HEARD THIS NEWS
ABOUT A MULTIVITAMIN STUDY
LOOKING AT LONG-TERM
HEALTH BENEFITS FOR MEN OVER 50.
THE ONE THEY USED
IN THAT STUDY...
CENTRUM SILVER.
THAT'S WHAT I TAKE.
MY DOCTOR!
HE KNOWS HIS STUFF.
[ Male Announcer ] CENTRUM.
THE MOST RECOMMENDED.
MOST PREFERRED.
MOST STUDIED.
CENTRUM,
ALWAYS YOUR MOST COMPLETE.
>> Gretchen: 23 MINUTES AFTER
THE TOP OF THE HOUR.
QUICK HEADLINES.
COULD JENNY RIVERA HAVE AVOIDED
DEATH?
IT TURNS OUT THE MEXICAN
AMERICAN SINGER MADE A LAST
MINUTE DECISION TO TAKE THAT
DEADLY PLANE RIDE.
SHE WAS OFFERED A ROOM FOR THE
NIGHT, BUT SHE DECIDED TO TAKE
OFF TO HER NEXT DESTINATI
>>> AND THE SHOW WON'T BE GOING
ON AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
MASSACHUSETTS.
THE TRADITIONAL HOLIDAY CONCERT
AT JORDAN JACKSON ELEMENTARY IN
MANSFIELD, GUESS WHAT?
IT'S BEEN CANCELED.
PARENTS COMPLAINED THAT LAST
YEAR'S PERFORMANCE WAS TOO
RELIGIOUS.
A SPEECH ON ANTI-BULLYING WILL
TAKE THE PLACE OF THE CONCERT IN
JANUARY.
CHRISTMAS?
BULLYING?
HH, I DON'T SEE A LOT OF
SIMILARITIES.
BUT THAT'S WHAT THEY'LL BE
DOING.
STEVE?
>> Steve: IT IS.
THANKS.
DON'T SPEND HUNDREDS OF DOLLARS
ON PROFESSIONAL HOLIDAY PICTURES
THIS YEAR.
WE'RE GOING TO SHOW YOU HOW YOU
CAN ACTUALLY TAKE THOSE SAME
PERFECT PICTURES WITH YOUR OWN
CAMERA.
THE PRESIDENT OF UNIQUE PHOTO IN
NEW JERSEY JOINS US NOW.
>> GREAT TO BE HERE.
>> Steve: WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A
LOT OF PICTURES OVER THE NEXT
COUPLE OF WEEKS AND THE AVERAGE
PERSON, WHETHER THEY GOT THE
FANCY SINGLE LENS REFLEX CAMERA
OR POINT AND SHOOT, THEY PUT IT
ON AUTOMATIC AND THEY JUST TAKE
ALL THEIR PICTURES.
THAT WINDS UP WITH A PICTURE
LIKE THIS WHERE IT'S IT'S A
FAMILY ACTION SHOT, BUT THE GIRL
IS A LITTLE DARK.
YOU CAN'T REALLY SEE WHAT'S
GOING ON OF THE HOW DO WE FIX
THAT?
>> TAKING PICTURES, IS WHAT WE
DO AT UNIQUE PHOTO.
WE REALLY TRY TO GET TO YOU WORK
ON TURNING THE CAMERA OFF THE
AUTOMATIC MODE.
GET INTO THE MANUAL MODES ON THE
CAMERA.
IN A TICKET LIKE THAT, THE
CAMERA SENSES THE LIGHT IN THE
AREA AND DOESN'T REALIZE THAT
YOU REALLY WANT A PICTURE OF THE
LOVELY YOUNG GIRL THAT'S THERE.
SO WHAT YOU DO IS YOU PUT THE
CAMERA IN A PROGRAM MODE, ROTATE
THE DIAL.
YOU FORCE THE FLASH TO FIRE IN
THE CAMERA.
CALLED FILL FLASH.
>> Steve: THE THING WITH -- NEXT
THING YOU KNOW, WHEN YOU LOOK AT
THAT, YOU CAN ACTUALLY SEE THE
DETAIL ON THE GIRL.
THAT'S BEAUTIFUL PICTURE.
LET'S COME DOWN TO THE NEXT ONE.
A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE GOING TO BE
PLAYING IN THE SNOW, BUT I HAVE
GOTTEN THIS PICTURE MANY, MANY
TIMES, SHOOTING THE KIDS,
PLAYING IN THE SNOW ON
AUTOMATIC.
IT SEEMS EVERYBODY IS A LITTLE
BLURRY.
>> YEAH.
THIS IS ONE OF THOSE THINGS
WHERE YOU WANT TO PUT THE CAMERA
IN ITS SHUTTER PRIORITY MODE
BECAUSE THE CAMERA WILL SENSE
THE BRIGHT SNOW AND BRIGHT LIGHT
AND WON'T PICK A SHUTTER SPEED
WHICH IS FAST ENOUGH.
THEN WHEN THE CHILDREN JUMP AND
THE SNOW GO UP IN THE AIR, THEY
BLUR.
SO YOU HAVE TO FORCE THE SHUT TO
GO SPEED FASTER.
YOU'LL SHOOT AT 1,000th OF A
SECRETARY.
>> Steve: IF I DON'T KNOW HOW IT
DO THE PRIORITY MODE, CAN I GO
INTO, IN MIAMI CAMERA HAS ICONS,
I CAN SWITCH AROUND?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
A LOT OF THE CAMERAS TODAY HAVE
PORT TRAIT MODE, SPORTS MODE,
ALL SORTS OF THINGS LIKE THAT.
THEY ADJUST THE CAMERAS REALLY,
REALLY WELL.
THEY COO A PRETTY GOOD JOB.
>> Steve: NOW, THIS WOULD BE IN
PORTRAIT MODE.
IT IS, WELL, NICELY LIGHTED.
BUT IT'S KIND OF AWKWARD, ISN'T
IT?
>> THIS IS A SOPHISTICATED
PICTURE TAKING CIRCUMSTANCE.
WE ENCOURAGE YOU TO --
>> THAT'S HOLDING A GLASS.
MAYBE NOT THE APPROPRIATE DRESS.
THE KID IS WEARING KIND OF A
NUTTY HAT.
>> ONE OF THE THINGS YOU WANT --
AS A PHOTOGRAPHER, IS YOU WANT
TO CONTROL YOUR SUBJECTS A
LITTLE BIT.
YOU WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT THEY
DON'T DO THINGS THAT THEY WANT
TO BE PHOTOGRAPHED IN 'CAUSE
THOSE PHOTOGRAPHS LAST FOREVER.
I'M NOT SURE THAT THE PERSON IN
THAT PHOTOGRAPH WANTS TO HAVE A
GLASS IN HER HAND OR WANTS TO
LOOK LIKE THAT.
THE FRAMING OF THE PICTURE,
REALLY AFFECTS IT.
>> Steve: THIS IS THE KIND OF
PICTURE YOU WOULD LIKE A
PORTRAIT TO WIND UP AT.
THERE SEEMS TO BE A DIFFERENT
DYNAMIC.
WHAT DID THE PHOTOGRAPHER TELL
THESE PEOPLE THAT THEY DIDN'T
TELL THE OTHERS?
>> HE TRIED TO GET THE
EXPRESSIONS UNIFORM.
THEY'RE ALL SMILING, THEY'RE ALL
DRESSED THE SAME.
HE'S FRAMED IT RIGHT.
WE'RE NOT CUTTING ANYBODY'S
HEADS OFF.
SO YOU CAN SEE THE PICTURE
PROVIDES A MUCH MORE HAPPY
MEMORY OF WHAT'S BEGUN ON.
THEY DON'T LOOK SO HAPPY IN THAT
PICTURE.
>> Steve: NO KIDDING.
MEANWHILE, IF YOU ARE LIKE CLARK
GRISWOLD, SPEND 25 DAYS GETTING
READY FOR CHRISTMAS, YOU HAVE
ALL YOUR LIGHTS ON YOUR HOUSE
AND YOU TAKE THAT PICTURE, IT'S
A LITTLE DARK.
IT PROBABLY SHOULD LOOK MORE
LIKE THIS.
HOW DO YOU GET THIS INSTEAD OF
THAT?
>> OKAY.
COUPLE OF THINGS YOU NEED TO DO
THIS.
FIRST OF ALL, YOU NEED A TIMED
EXPOSURE.
ONE THAT'S LONGER THAN WHAT THE
CAMERA WOULD SET UP.
IN THIS CASE, THE CAMERA FOCUSES
ON THE LIGHTS ON THE HOUSE, SO
IT FOOLS THE CAMERA INTO
THINKING THE PICTURE IS
BRIGHTER.
SO YOU GET A NICE CANON CAMERA
LIKE THAT AND A TRI POD.
SET IT UP.
YOU SET IT INTO THAT SHUTTER
PRIORITY MODE AND YOU FORCE THE
SHUTTER TO STAY OPEN A LITTLE
LONGER, IT'S CALLED DRAGGING THE
SHUTTER.
YOU'LL GET A MUCH MORE COMPOSED
PICTURE.
THE SHUTTER SPEED, YOU'LL PLAY
WITH IT A LITTLE BIT.
THE OTHER TRICK IN THAT PICTURE,
AND THIS IS A REALLY, REALLY
GOOD TIP, IS THAT THIS PICTURE
IS TAKEN SORT OF, YOU HAVE YOUR
CHRISTMAS DINNER, YOU GO OUT AND
FEELING GOOD AND GO OUT AND TAKE
A PICTURE OF YOUR LIGHTS.
THIS IS TAKEN RIGHT AFTER
SUNDOWN.
>> Steve: THAT'S GOOD.
THAT WAY YOU CAN SEE THE BLUE
SKY.
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
>> Steve: I KNOW THE LITTLE
POINT AND SHOOTS CAN BE 50, 60
BUCKS.
IF YOU WANT A NICE CAMERA, LOW
END, TO TAKE FANTASTIC PICTURES,
HOW MUCH?
>> $700, $800 RANGE, WHICH IT
ALLOWS TO YOU TAKE A VARIETY OF
PICTURES.
THIS IS A MORE PROFESSIONAL, THE
PANASONIC GH 3, A $1,300 CAMERA.
>> Steve: OH, BOY.
UNIQUE PHOTOS, GET THE BIG
CAMERA SHOW.
>> NEW JERSEY, LARGEST CAMERA
STORE.
WE HAVE AN AMAZING CAMERA SHOW.
NEW JERSEY CAMERA SHOW, 50
VENDORS.
40 FREE CLASSES THIS WEEKEND.
COME ON DOWN TO FAIRFIELD, NEW
JERSEY, WE'D LOVE TO SEE YOU.
>> Steve: MATT, GOOD JOB.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Steve: THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
MEANWHILE, SMILE AS YOU LISTEN
TO THIS.
NEXT UP ON THE RUNDOWN, ACTOR
HARRY BELAFONTE HAS ADVICE FOR
THE PRESIDENT.
ACT MORE LIKE A DICTATOR.
THAT, PLUS HARRY'S GREATEST
GAFFES STRAIGHT AHEAD.  WHAT IS
HE TALKING ABOUT THIS TIME?
WORK OUT WHILE YOU WORK?
HOW YOU CAN BURN CALORIES WHILE
DOING YOUR WORK IN THE OFFICE OR
AT HOME WATCHING TV.
YOU CAN'T ARGUE WITH
NUTRITION YOU CAN SEE.
GREAT GRAINS.
GREAT GRAINS CEREAL STARTS
WHOLE AND STAYS WHOLE.
SEE THE SEAM?
MORE PCESSED FLAKES LOOK
NOTHING LIKE NATURAL GRAINS.
I'M EATING WHAT I KN
IS BETTER NUTRITION.
MMMM. GREAT GRAINS.
SEARCH GREAT GRAINS
AND SEE FOR YOURSELF.
TIME FOR CITI PRICE REWIND.
BECAUSE YOUR DAUGHTER REALLY
WANTS THAT PINK CASTLE THING.
AND YOU REALLDON'T WANT
TO PAY MORE THAN YOU HAVE TO.
ONLY CITI PRICE REWIND
AUTOMATICALLY SEARCHES
FOR THE LOWEST PRICE.
AND IF IT FINDONE, YOU GET
REFUNDED THE DIFFERENCE.
JUST USE YOUR CITI CARD
AND REGISTER YOUR PURCHASE
ONLINE.
HAVE A SUPER SPARKLY DAY!
OK.
[ Male Announcer ] NOW ALL
YOUEED IS A MAGIC CARRIAGE.
CITI PRICE REWIND.
START SAVING
AT CITI.COM/PRICEREWIND.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Sharable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
NESPRESSO.
WHERE I NEVER HAVE TO COMPROMISE
ON ANYTHING.
♪
WHERE JUST ONE TOUCH
CREATES THE PERFECT COFFEE.
WHERE EVERY CAPPUCCINO AND LATTE
IS ONLY MADE WITH FRESH MILK.
AND WHERE THE STAFF
IS EXCEPTIONALLY FRIENDLY.
♪
NESPRESSO. WHAT ELSE?
YOU WON'T TAKE OUR FUTURE.
AIDS AFFECTS US ALL.
EVEN BABIES.
CHEVRON IS WORKING TO STOP
MOTHER-TO-CHILD TRANSMISSION.
OUR EMPLOYEES AND THEIR FAMILIES
ARE PART OF THE FIGHT.
AND WE'RE WINNING.
AT CHEVRON NIGERIA, WE HAVEN'T
HAD A REPORTED CASE IN 12EARS.
AIDS IS STRONG.
BUT WE ARE STRONGER.
AND AIDS...
♪
AIDS IS GOING TO LOSE.
He's going to apply testosterone
to his underarm.
AXIRON, the only underarm
treatment for low T,
can restore testosterone levels
back to normal in most men.
AXIRON is not for use in women
or anyone younger than 18.
AXIRON can transfer to
others through direct contact.
Women, especially those who are
or who may become pregnant,
and children should avoid
contact where AXIRON is applied
as unexpected signs of puberty
in children or changes
in body hair or increased
acne in women may occur.
Report these signs and symptoms
to your doctor if they occur.
Tell your doctor about
all medical conditions
and medications.
Do not use if you have prostate
or breast cancer.
Serious side effects
could include
increased risk
of prostate cancer;
worsening prostate symptoms;
decreased sperm count;
ankle, feet, or body swelling;
enlarged or painful breasts;
problems breathing while
sleeping;
and blood clots in the legs.
Common side effects include
skin redness
or irritation where applied,
increased
red blood cell count,
headache, diarrhea, vomiting,
and increase in PSA.
See your doctor,
and for a 30-day free trial,
go to Axiron.com.
>> RETIREMENT SPEECH YESTERDAY,
SENATOR JOE LIEBERMAN SAID WHEN
HE FIRST JOINED THE SENATE,
BLACKBERRY WAS A FRUIT AND
TWEETING WAS SOMETHING BIRDS
DID.
[ LAUGHTER ]
IT'S FUNNY.
IT GOT ANNOYING WHEN HE KEPT
GIVING MORE EXAMPLES FOR SIX
MORE HOURS.
GOING ON-LINE WITH WHAT HE DID
AT THE SUPERMARKET.
GOOGLE IS WHAT YOU DID WHEN A
PRETTY GIRL WALKS BY!
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Gretchen: OH, MY GOSH.
>> Steve: HE DIDN'T STOP.
HE HAD IT GOING.
>> Gretchen: THERE IS SOMETHING
ABOUT THE FRUIT WITH THE THINGS,
WHEN I FIRST GOT ONE, MY
DAUGHTER SAID TO ME, MAMA, SHE
SAID, WHEN YOU GOING TO PUT DOWN
THE BLUEBERRY?
>> Brian: YEAH.
>> Gretchen: SHE DIDN'T WANT ME
TO GET AN iPHONE.
THAT WAS A VERY STRONG
INDICATION THAT MOMMY DIDN'T
PICK UP THE BLUEBERRY VERY OFTEN
WHEN AT HOME WITH KIDS.
>> Steve: REMEMBER THE GUY WHO
SANG DOE.
♪ DEO
♪ .
>> IS THAT THE ONLY SONG DID HE?
>> Steve: THAT WAS HIS BIG SONG
HE LIVED OFF EVER SINCE.
HARRY, PICTURED THERE, STOPPED
BY -- WHO IS HE WITH THERE?
STOPPED BY THE AL SHARPTON SHOW
OVER ON MSDNC A COUPLE OF DAYS
AGO AND HE WAS TALKING A LITTLE
BIT ABOUT WHAT THE PRESIDENT
SHOULD DO WITH ALL THOSE PEOPLE
WHO ON THE RIGHT, OPPOSE SOME OF
HIS POLICIES.
HERE IS WHAT MR. DEO SAID.
>> FASCINATES ME IS THAT
MILLIONS OF AMERICANS EXPRESSING
THEIR DESIRE TO STIFF -- THAT
THERE SHOULD BE THIS LINGERING
INFESTATION OF REALLY CORRUPT
PEOPLE WHO SIT TRYING TO
DISMANTLE THE WISHES OF THE
PEOPLE, THE MANDATE THAT HAS
BEEN GIVEN TO BARAK OBAMA, AND I
DON'T KNOW WHAT MORE THEY WANT.
THE ONLY THING LEFT FOR OBAMA TO
DO IS TO BE LIKE A THIRD WORLD
DICTATOR AND THROW THESE GUYS IN
JAIL.
>> Steve: THROW THEM IN JAIL.
>> Brian: IF THE PRESIDENT GETS
RELIE DETECTORRED, HE SHOULD BE
ABLE TO DO WHATEVER HE WANTS.
DID HE FEEL THE SAME WAY ABOUT
GEORGE BUSH WHEN HE WON BAY
WIDER MARGIN?
WHAT ABOUT ALL THE DEMOCRATS
THAT GOT IN HIS WAY?
SHOULD THEY HAVE BEEN JAILED?
>> Steve: SPEAK OF DICTATORS,
HE'S KNOWN A FEW.
REMEMBER IN 2006 HE ACTUALLY
WENT DOWN TO VISIT CHAVEZ IN
VENEZUELA AND REFERRED TO GEORGE
W. BUSH AS THE BIGGEST TRYST IN
THE WORLD.
>> Brian: THAT WAS FANTASTIC.
>> Gretchen: HERE IS A DIFFERENT
QUOTE WHERE HE CALLED HOMELAND
SECURITY THE GESTAPO.
CITIZENS ARE HAVING THEIR RIGHTS
SUSPENDED.
YOU CAN BE ARRESTED AND NOT
CHARGED, YOU CAN BE ARRESTED AND
HAVE NO RIGHT TO COUNSEL.
>> Brian: YOU MEAN THOSE CHARGES
THAT -- THOSE ACTS, LIKE THE
PATRIOT ACT THAT PRESIDENT OBAMA
LEFT IN PLACE?
THAT'S THE PERIOD OF AMERICA?
HERE HE IS SAYING SOMETHING
ELSE.
PRAISING A COP KILLER.
LISTEN.
>> SUCH IS THE CASE WITH JAMAL,
HE IS NOT GUILTY OF THE CRIME
FOR WHICH HE HAS BEEN CHARGED.
HE DID NOT COMMIT THE CRIMES.
HE HAS BEEN CHARGED WITH.
THOSE WHO PROSECUTED HIM KNOW
THAT.
IF IT'S UP TO US, CITIZENS THE
WORLD WHO CARE ABOUT JUSTICE TO
STAY THE COURSE, TO MAKE SURE
THAT HE IS RELEASED.
>> Steve: FREEDOM OF SPEECH,
HARRY BELAFONTE.
>> Gretchen: NOW TO YOUR
HEADLINE THIS MORNING.
ONE OF THE ONLY LIVING MEDAL OF
HONOR RECIPIENTS RECOVERING FROM
A BRUTAL ATTACK.
DETAILS ON THE ATTACK ON DAKOTA
MYER.
WE KNOW AN 18-YEAR-OLD HAS BEEN
CHARGED WITH ASSAULT.
HE WAS AWARD THE MILITARY
HIGHEST HORN BY PRESIDENT OBAMA
LAST YEAR.
HE'S CREDITED WITH SAVING THE
LIVES OF 13 AMERICANS AND 23
AFGHAN SOLDIERS DURING A FIRE
FIGHT IN 2009.
>> Steve: SHE'S ACCUSED OF DRUNK
DRIVING IN MAINE.
BUT SALLY STRUTHERS SAYS SHE
DIDN'T DO IT.
OH, GLORIA.
HER LAWYER HAS ENTERED A NOT
GUILTY PLEA FOR HER.
SHE WAS ARRESTED IN SEPTEMBER IN
MAINE WHERE SHE FREQUENTLY PLAYS
A ROLE IN THE MUSICAL "NINE TO
FIVE."
SHE'S SCHEDULED TO BE BACK IN
COURT IN FEBRUARY.
>> Brian: I DIDN'T KNOW "NINE TO
FIVE" WAS PLAYING IN MAINE.
A NEW STUDY FINDS CHILDREN BORN
WITH A C SECTION ARE MORE LIKELY
TO EAT FATTY FOODS AND BECOME
OVERWEIGHT LATER IN LIFE.
RESEARCHERS LOOKED AT NINE
STUDIES OF OVER 200,000 PEOPLE
AND FOUND WHEN BORN BY C
SECTION, THE BABIES WERE 33%
MORE LIKELY TO BECOME HEAVY.
BUT THEY SAY THIS DOESN'T MEAN
THAT A CAESAREAN CAUSED THE
BABIES TO GAIN WEIGHT.
IT'S EASY ON THE BABY THROUGH A
C SECTION.
>> Gretchen: REALLY?
>> Brian: YEAH.
EASIER ON THE BABY.
>> Gretchen: ON THE MOM,
DIFFERENT STORY.
BUT LET'S NOT GET INTO THAT
RIGHT NOW.
A JESUS LOOK ALIKE TOSSED OUT OF
A SPORTING EVENT IN ENGLAND.
ALL RIGHT.
SO YOU SEE THAT IMAGE THERE.
THAT'S NATHAN GRINNEDLE BEING
ESCORTED BY POLICE.
THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE AT THE
PROFESSIONAL DARTS TOURNAMENT
BEGAN CHANTING JESUS, JESUS!
WHEN THEY SAW HIM.
ORGANIZERS SAID IT WAS TOO
DISTRACTING TO THE PLAYERS, SO
THEY ASKED HIM TO LEAVE?
MAYBE HE SHOULD HAVE STUCK
AROUND FOR A LITTLE INSPIRATION
FOR THE DART THROWING.
EXACTLY!
THEY COULD HAVE PLAYED THIS
MUSIC AND MAYBE THEY WOULD HAVE
DONE BETTER.
>> Brian: WHEN JESUS DOES COME
BACK, SHOULD WE GREET HIM WITH A
CHANT?
>> Gretchen: YOU'RE NOT GOING TO
KNOW.
YOU NEED TO GO TO CONFESSION A
FEW MORE TIMES BEFORE THAT'S
GOING TO HAPPEN.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Steve: WITH A POLICE ESCORT.
>> Brian: IT'S DANGEROUS.
COULD CAUSE A RIOT.
>> Steve: THOSE DARTS GUYS,
THEY'VE GOT TO CONCENTRATE,
PLEASE.
>> Brian: PLEASE, JESUS.
ENOUGH.
>> Steve: ALL RIGHT.
STRAIGHT AHEAD ON THIS FRIDAY,
JUST IN TIME FOR CHRISTMAS, AND
THE HOLIDAYS, WORKERS AT ONE OF
THE NATION'S BUSIEST AIRPORTS
THREATENING TO GO ON STRIKE.
LATE BREAKING DETAILS THAT COULD
SLOW YOU DOWN AS YOU THEY HAD
GRANDMA'S HOUSE.
>> Gretchen: THEN NO SUCH THING
AS A PRIVATE CONVERSATION ON
SOME BUSES BECAUSE BIG BROTHER
IS LISTENING.
IS THAT EVEN LEGAL?
PETER JOHNSON, JR. NEXT.
FIRST, SHEAR ALISYN WITH WHAT'S
ON TAP FOR THE WEEKEND.
HI, YOU'RE ON THE BIKE?
>> YOU KNOW HOW MUCH I LOVE
WORKING OUT.
>> Gretchen: NO, YOU DON'T.
>> AND I'M HOSTING THE 9:00 A.M.
SHOW TODAY.
SO I THINK I'M GOING TO DO IT
FROM HERE.
KILL TWO BIRDS WITH ONE STONE.
ON THE WEEKEND, HERE IS WHAT'S
COMING UP.
A MEDICAL TEST THAT TAKES
SECONDS AND YOU CAN DO IT RIGHT
NOW AT HOME OR AT WORK AND THE
OUTCOME WILL DETERMINE HOW LONG
YOU'LL LIVE.
ALSO D IS FOR DIVORCE?
SESAME STREET IS TEACHING KIDS
ALL ABOUT DIVORCE.
IS THAT A GOOD IDEA?
THAT'S ALL THIS WEEKEND STARTING
AT 6:00 A.M. EASTERN.
SEE YOU THEN
.so as you can see,s
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
TRY RUNNING FOUR.NING
A RESTAURANT IS HARD,
FORTUNATELY WE'VE GOT INK.
IT GIVES US 5X THE REWARDS
ON OUR INTERNET, PHONE
CHARGES AND CABLE,
PLUS AT OFFICE SUPPLY STORES.
REWARDS WE PUT RIGHT
BACK INTO OUR BUSINESS.
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
WE'VE EVER WANTED TO DO
AND INK HELPS US DO IT.
MAKE YOUR MARK
WITH INK FROM CHASE.
>> Brian: HUNDREDS OF PRIVATE
SECURITY WORKERS IN NEW YORK JFK
AIRPORT THREATENING TO WALK OFF
THE JOB JUST DAYS BEFORE
CHRISTMAS IF THEIR DEMANDS
AREN'T MET.
NOW MORE WITH WHAT THIS COULD
MEAN FOR HOLIDAY TRAVELERS.
LYDIA?
>> GOOD MORNING, BRIAN.
EXACTLY RIGHT.
THIS STRIKE COULD HAPPEN FIVE
DAYS BEFORE CHRISTMAS.
300 WORKERS COULD GO ON STRIKE.
THESE PRIVATE SECURITY GUARDS,
THEY ARE NONUNIONIZED WORKERS.
RIGHT NOW WE STILL DON'T KNOW
EXACTLY WHAT THIS COULD ALL MEAN
FOR TRAVELERS.
THEY HAVE VERY IMPORTANT JOBS
HERE AT JFK AIRPORT.
THEY ACTUALLY CONTROL THE
TRAFFIC HERE IN FRONT OF THE
TERMINALS.
THEY ALSO GUARD ALARM DOORS.
SO IF THIS COULD HAPPEN, IF THIS
DOES HAPPEN, A LOT OF TRAVELERS
WE SPOKE TO ARE EXTREMELY
WORRIED ABOUT IT.
AGAIN, THEY ARE NONUNION
WORKERS, BUT THEY ARE BEING
BACKED BY ONE OF THE LARGEST
UNIONS IN THE COUNTRY.
FOR NOW, THAT'S THE LATEST HERE
AT JFK.
BRIAN, BACK TO YOU.
>> Brian: THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
GRETCH?
>> Gretchen: NEXT TIME YOU RIDE
THE BUS, BE CAREFUL WHAT YOU SAY
BECAUSE BIG BROTHER MAY BE
LISTENING TO YOU ON THE BUS?
GOVERNMENT OFFICIALS ARE
INSTALLING AUDIO SURVEILLANCE ON
PUBLIC BUSES ACROSS THE COUNTRY,
GIVING THEM THE ABILITY TO
RECORD ANY AND ALL
CONVERSATIONS.
SO SHOULD PUBLIC SAFETY TRUMP
YOUR RIGHT TO PRIVACY?
GINNING -- JOINING ME, PETER
JOHNSON, JR.
WHY ARE THEY DOING THIS?
>> I GUESS THERE HAVE BEEN
CRIMES ON THESE BUSS AND THERE
HAVE BEEN ISSUES WITH THE BUS
DRIVERS AND SOME OF THE UNIONS
ARE SAYING, LISTEN, YOU GOT TO
PROTECT OUR BUS DRIVERS.
WHAT'S HAPPENING, THOUGH, IS
THAT YOUR RIGHT TO PRIVACY,
LIMITED AS IT IS IN PUBLIC
SITUATIONS, IS GOING TO GO OUT
THE WINDOW IN PLACES LIKE SAN
FRANCISCO ON THE TROLLEY CARS,
DURHAM, EUGENE, OREGON,
COLUMBUS, HARTFORD, ATHENS,
OTHER CITIES AROUND THE COUNTRY.
THE D.H.S., DEPARTMENT OF
HOMELAND SECURITY, AND CITY AND
LOCAL AND STATE AUTHORITIES ARE
PUTTING MONEY TOGETHER TO TAPE
YOUR CONVERSATIONS ON BUSES.
>> Gretchen: WHY CAN'T THEY PUT
UP A CAMERA TO HELP US IF
THEY'RE WORRIED ABOUT THE BUS
DRIVER?
>> YOU'RE RIGHT.
THEY HAVE CAMERAS.
NOW THEY'RE INTEGRATING AUDIO.
NOW THEY'RE INTEGRATING THAT IT
CAN GO OUT ON THE WEB TO A DEPOT
SOMEWHERE ELSE, TO A POLICE
FACILITY, TO SOMEONE THAT CAN
LISTEN TO YOUR CONVERSATION WITH
YOUR CHILDREN ON THE BUS.
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT SCHOOL,
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT GOING TO
SEE A RELATIVE, GOING TO SEE
YOUR MOTHER, AND ALL OF THAT
STUFF BECOMES PART OF THE ETHER.
>> Gretchen: I'M GLAD YOU DIDN'T
SAY I WAS TALKING TO MY HUSBAND
ABOUT DATE NIGHT.
>> I DIDN'T SAY THAT AT ALL.
>> Gretchen: THAT MIGHT BE MORE
PRIVATE.
>> IT WOULD BE PRIVATE, BUT ALL
OF THAT IS PRIVATE.
SO NOW WE HAVE A SITUATION IN
THIS COUNTRY WHERE YES, THERE
SHOULD BE SOME LIMITATIONS ON
WHAT GOES ON IN PUBLIC
FACILITIES.
WE SEE IN AIRPORTS.
WE SEE IT IN CERTAIN CABS WHERE
THEY HAVE CAMERAS.
BUT NOW OUR CONVERSATION WILL BE
MONITORED.
>> Gretchen: IS IT LEGAL?
>> IN THE END IT MAY BE LEGAL.
IN THE END, THE GOVERNMENT MAY
FIND A WAY AROUND THE FOURTH
AMENDMENT BECAUSE THEY'RE
SAYING, WE'RE GIVING YOU WARNING
THAT WE'RE LISTENING TO YOU.
WHAT KIND OF COUNTRY IS IT WHERE
WE SAY, IT'S OKAY TO LISTEN TO
YOU BECAUSE WE'VE TOLD YOU THAT
WE'RE GOING TO LISTEN TO YOU?
HOW FAR IS THE STANDARD BEING
DEVIATED THAT WE'RE SAYING,
YEAH, WE CAN ACCEPT THAT?
WHAT DO WE ACCEPT NEXT?
IN LIBRARIES, IN DOCTORS'
OFFICES?
DO WE ACCEPT IT IN THE STUDIOS
AND IN THE OFFICES OF FOX NEWS
OR NBC NEWS?
WHERE DO WE LIMIT THIS IN TERMS
OF EAVESDROPPING?
AND TO SAY, OKAY, WE NEED TO
PROTECT OUR BUS DRIVERS.
I AGREE.
BUT AT WHAT COST DO WE DO THAT?
IS VIDEO ENOUGH, AS YOU SAY?
>> Gretchen: LET ME ASK YOU
THIS, WHAT KIND OF WARNING --
BECAUSE FOR EXAMPLE, I'M
THINKING OF DRUG WARNINGS.
THEY SAY THEM REALLY, REALLY
FAST AT THEnd OF TV
COMMERCIALS OR REALLY, REALLY
TINY FINE PRINT.
WHAT KIND OF WARNING --
>> THERE ARE SIGNS UP ON THESE
BUSES THAT SAY YOUR CONVERSATION
IS GOING TO BE LISTENED TO.
BUT SHOULD WE SIT IN SILENCE ON
THE BUS?
THE BUS,  WHICH IS THE HALLMARK
OF CIVIL RIGHTS IN THIS COUNTRY,
REMEMBER ROSA PARKS?
YOU CAN GO TO A MUSEUM IN DEAR
BORN, MICHIGAN AND SEE THAT BUS,
ABOUT GOING TO THE BACK OF THE
BUS.
DO WE ALL NOW SIT SILENTLY ON
THE BUS BECAUSE WE'RE AFRAID
THAT OUR GOVERNMENT IS LISTENING
TO OUR CONVERSATIONS ABOUT
GROCERIES, ABOUT FAMILY
PROBLEMS, ABOUT DATE NIGHT,
ABOUT WHO WE'RE VOTING FOR FOR
PRESIDENT, ABOUT WHAT WE INTEND
TO BE DOING?
FINE.
IF THERE IS A TERRORIST RISK,
THEN THERE IS A NOTCH IN THE LAW
TO ALLOW THAT.
BUT TO HAVE AMERICANS
EAVESDROPPED ON ON A DAILY BASIS
GOING FROM WORK TO WORK, TO
CHURCH, FROM CHURCH, THAT, I
THINK, IS A REAL, REAL PROBLEM
THAT WE'VE GOT TO GRAPPLE WITH
IT.
THE GOVERNMENT MAY FIND AN
EXCUSE FOR IT.
BUT I DON'T FIND ANY EXCUSE FOR
IT AT ALL.
>> Gretchen: INTERESTING DEBATE.
HAVE A GREAT WEEKEND.
>> GOOD TO SEE YOU.
>> Gretchen: REACHED OUT TO THE
DHS FOR STATEMENT.
HAVEN'T HEARD BACK YET ON THAT
STORY.
>>> OKAY, YOU WANT TO WORK OUT
WHILE YOU WORK?
HOW CAN YOU BURN IT ALL OFF?
LOOK AT STEVE AND BRIAN.
I TOLD YOU GUYS MY SKIRT IS TOO
TIGHT.
FIRST LET'S CHECK IN WITH BILL
HEMMER.
TELL BUS YOUR SPECIAL COMING UP
THIS WEEKEND.
>> THOSE GUYS HAVE MILES TO GO.
GRETCHEN, IT'S THE COUNTDOWN TO
DOOMSDAY.
HAVE YOU HEARD?
THE MAYAN CALENDAR IS ABOUT TO
EXPIRE.
SUNDAY NIGHT, 9:00 O'CLOCK,
CHECK IT OUT RIGHT HERE ON THE
FOX NEWS CHANNEL.
GREAT STUFF FROM ALL OVER THE
WORLD.
SEE YOU THEN.
IN THE MEANTIME, COMING UP FOR
US IN TEN MINUTE, AMERICAN
MARINE BEING HELD IN MEXICO.
WE'LL TALK TO HIS ATTORNEY ABOUT
THE POSSIBILITY OF A RELEASE.
TODAY IS THE DEADLINE ON A MAJOR
PART OF OBAMACARE.
WHAT IS YOUR STATE DOING?
SOME WONDER IF WE'LL EVER LEARN
THE TRUTH ABOUT LIBYA.
I'LL EXPLAIN THE LATEST MOVES BY
THE ADMINISTRATION AND WHAT JOHN
BOEHNER IS DOING THIS WEEKEND
MIGHT TELL US A WHOLE LOT ABOUT
OUR OWN FUTURE HERE.
SEE YOU IN TEN MINUTES ON
"AMERICA'S NEWSROOM"
[ Male Announcer ]
COUGHEQUENCE™ #8.
WAKING THE BABY.
[ coughs ]
[ baby crying ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
ROBITUSSIN® LIQUID FORMULA
SOOTHES YOUR THROAT ON CONTACT
AND THE ACTIVE INGREDIENT
RELIEVES YOUR COUGH.
ROBITUSSIN®. DON'T SUFFER
THE COUGHEQUENCES™.
PREGO?!
BUT I'VE BOUGHT RAGU FOR YEARS.
[ Thinking ] WONDER WHAT OTHER
QUESTIONABLE CHOICES I'VE MADE?
I CHOOSE DATE NUMBER 2!
WHOOO!
[ sigh of relief ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHOOSE TASTE. CHOOSE PREGO.
GIVES YOU 1% CASH BACK
ON ALL PURCHASES,
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS.
AND EVERYONE...BUT HER
LIKES 50% MORE CASH.
BUT I'M UPPING MY GAME.
DO YOU WANT A CANDY CANE?
YES!
DO YOU WANT THE PUPPY?
DO YOU WANT A TRICYCLE?
YES!
DO YOU WANT
50 PERCENT MORE CASH?
NO!
♪
FESTIVE.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE Capital One
Cash Rewards Card
GIVES YOU
1% CASH BACK
ON EVERY
PURCHASE
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS
ON THE CASH YOU EARN.
IT'S THE CARD FOR PEOPLE
WHO LIKE MORE CASH.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
>> Gretchen: WELCOME BACK.
HAVE YOU EVER USED THE EXCUSE, I
HAVE TOO MUCH WORK TO WORK OUT?
THANKS TO OUR NEXT GUEST, THE
EXCUSES NO LONGER IS A GOOD ONE?
>> Brian: WHO IS THAT NEXT
GUEST?
I BELIEVE IT'S RYAN MOORE, THE
CEO AND FOUNDER OF REBO
INNOVATION.
>> YEAH.
>> Gretchen: HE'S HERE TO SHOW
YOU HOW YOU CAN WORK OUT FROM
THE COMFORT OF YOUR OWN DESK.
HOW DID YOU COME UP WITH THE
IDEA?
>> CLOSE FRIEND OF OURS PASSED
AWAY FROM CANCER.
WE WERE INSPIRED TO JOIN
100-MILE, THREE MOUNTAIN BICYCLE
CHALLENGE.
BUT WE NEEDED TO TRAIN.
WE WERE HAVING A HARD TIME
RUNNING OUR BUSINESS, GETTING
OUR WORK DONE WHILE CYCLING
INDOORS AND TRAINING.
SO WE LOOKED FOR A DEVICE THAT
WOULD ALLOW TO US MOUNT OR
COMPUTERS, BUT NOTHING EXISTED,
SO WE MADE OUR OWN.
AFTER TRAINING FOR THE EVENT
EXCLUSIVELY USING WHAT WE MADE
AND RIDING IT, WE THOUGHT HEY,
THIS IS A GREAT IDEA.
IT REALLY WORKS.
>> Steve: IT REALLY DOES WORK.
AND BRIAN WAS TALKING EARLIER
ABOUT HOW WHEN HE WORKS OUT AT
THE GYM, HE'S ALWAYS READING.
BUT WHAT I'VE NOTICED IS, AND
THIS IS GREAT BECAUSE YOU'VE GOT
A LAPTOP HERE -- IS IT'S OFTEN
SHAKY.
SO IT'S HARD TO READ.
IF YOU COME UP WITH THIS DESK
THING, FOAMY AND I'M SURE NASA
HELPED YOU DEVELOP IT, THE
COMPUTER STAYS ABSOLUTELY ROCK
STEADY WHILE YOU'RE GOING AS
FAST AS YOU POSSIBLY CAN.
>> RIGHT.
WE DESIGNED THIS SO IT WAS A LOW
INTENSITY.
HAD A SHORT THRONE SO IT
WOULDN'T SHAKE THE COMPUTER TOO
MUCH.
>> Brian: I'VE BEEN FEELING THE
QUADS OF A LOT OF THE PEOPLE ON
OUR STAFF, SO I SAID WE NEED TO
FIRM UP.
LET'S SEE IF WE'RE TRYING TO
BUILD SOME THIGH POWER.
GO TO THE NEWS ROOM AS WELL
WHERE THE WORKOUTS ARE APLENTY.
>> Gretchen: LOOK, YES.
WE FORCE OUR PEOPLE TO SWEAT
WHILE THEY ACTUALLY PUT TOGETHER
THE SHOW.
ACTUALLY SOMETIMES THEY'RE
SWEATING WITHOUT WORKING OUT.
>> Brian: THIS THING FOLDS UP
QUICK, RIGHT?
HOW DOES IT FOLD UP?
>> YOU JUST PUSH IT TOGETHER AND
IT SNAPS.
JUST LIKE THAT.
HAS WHEELS.
YOU CAN TRANSPORT IT, MOVE IT
AROUND.
WEIGHS 35 POUNDS.
>> Steve: ONE OF THE GREAT
THINGS IS YOU'VE GOT A MILEAGE
THING ON IT SO YOU CAN FIGURE
OUT AT THE END OF THE DAY HOW
FAR YOU'VE GONE.
I KNOW YOU'VE SOLD SO FAR, AND
THEY SELL FOR $250.
YOU CAN GET THEM ON AMAZON.
YOU'VE SOLD 6,000 SO FAR.
HAS ANYBODY E-MAILED YOU AND
SAID OKAY, TODAY AT WORK I WENT
179 MILES, OR WHAT THE BIGGEST
NUMBER IS?
>> WE GET A LOT OF REPORTS OF
THAT.
PEOPLE WILL CLOCK 200, 300 MILES
OVER THE COURSE OF A MONTH.
WE LOVE TO HEAR THAT.
SOME PEOPLE ARE COMPETING USING
THAT.
>> Brian: I'VE HAD IN.
I STICK THIS ON THE BIKE AND IF
IT GOES OVER THE LIP, YOU HAVE
TO BE -- HAVE THE REFLEXES OF A
WIDE RECEIVER IN ORDER TO STOP
IT.
THAT'S A GOOD JOB.
AGAIN, THE ENTREPRENEURIAL
SPIRIT MIXING WITH NECESSITY.
>> YES.
WE LOVE TO HEAR THE MOST IS WHEN
PEOPLE WRITE US BACK AFTER THEY
USED FOR A YEAR.
THEY SAY I'M DEALING WITH MY
MULTIPLE SCLEROSIS OR MET A
WEIGHT LOSS GOAL.
WE MET A GENTLEMAN WHILE
STUDYING FOR HIS BAR EXAM USED
THIS FOR 90 MINUTE ACIDY FOR 12
MONTHS AND LOST 45 POUNDS AND IS
CONTINUING TO MEET HIS GOALS.
>> Steve: YOU KNOW, ONE OF THE
SPECIAL THINGS IS YOU'VE GOT THE
SOFTEST BIKE SEAT EVER.
A LOT OF THOSE BIKE SEATS ARE
HARD AND DOESN'T FEEL GOOD BACK
THERE.
THIS IS GREAT.
IT'S LIKE A CLOUD.
>> Brian: IT'S A GREAT BUTT
CUSHION IS WHAT YOU'RE SAYING.
>> Steve: IT'S LIKE A CLOUD.
>> Brian: OKAY, FINE.
>> Gretchen: I WISH I COULD TRY
IT OUT, BUT I WORE A SKIRT
TODAY.
OKAY.
SO WAIT.
IT'S $249?
AND IT'S REINNOVATION.
>> IT'S CALLED THE FIT DESK.
>> Gretchen: WE'LL BE RIGHT
BACK.
>> Steve: CREW, GO FASTER!
FAST
ER!
[ Woman ] Ring. Ring.
Progresso.
. .
Tomato basil.
Potato with bacon.
We've got
a lotta empty cans.
[ Male Announcer ] Hear from
our chefs on Facebook
this Friday!
AND NOW -- I GOT
A GREAT NEW WAY TO GET DEALS.
IT'S CALLED BANKAMERIDEALS,
FROM BANK OF AMERICA.
I CHOOSE THE CASH BACK DEALS
IN MY MOBILE OR ONLINE BANKING.
I JUST USE MY BANK OF AMERICA
DEBIT OR CREDIT CARD WHEN I PAY.
AND I GET AS MUCH
AS 15% CASH BACK --
PUT INTO MY ACCOUNT.
THIS IS CASH BACK ON TOP OF
OTHER REWARDS I ALREADY GET.
BEST OF ALL -- IT'S FREE.
HAPPY HOLIDAYS.
[ Male Announcer ]
INTRODUCING BANKAMERIDEALS,
FREE FOR
ONLINE BANKING CUSTOMERS.
SIGN IN TO YOUR ONLINE BANKING
TO CHOOSE YOUR DEALS TODAY.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Sharable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.