MEGYN: IT IS A SOURCE OF BAD
CLICHES.
TOO MANY TO MENTION.
WE'RE ALL PROBABLY TIRED OF
THE TERM FISCAL CLIFF BUT
APPARENTLY EVERYONE IS NOT
AFFECTED IN THE SAME WAY.
JON: RIGHT.
>> THE NAPA VALLEY WINERY,
THE CLIFFSIDE WINERY, THE
CLIFFSIDE, WINERY, ORDER
FROM D.C., MARYLAND,
VIRGINIA ARE UP 15% SINCE
THE FISCAL CLIFF DEBATE
CAUGHT ON.
THEY TOLD "THE WALL STREET
JOURNAL" A LOT OF CUSTOMERS
ARE MENTIONING THE FISCAL
CLIFF WHEN THEY PLACE THEIR
ORDERS.
NO WORD ON DRINKING GAMES.
JON: SOMEBODY HAS MONEY TO
SPEND.
THANKS FOR JOINING US.
>> THEY'RE ALL IN D.C.
INTERESTING.
"AMERICA LIVE" STARTS RIGHT
NOW.
MEGYN: FOX NEWS ALERT ON THE
INVESTIGATION INTO THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
A NEW REPORT TODAY SAYS
POLICE HAVE YET TO FIND ANY
EVIDENCE THAT THE ACCUSED
GUNMAN WAS ON MEDICATION FOR
MY MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES.
WELCOME TO "AMERICA LIVE",
EVERYONE.
I'M MEGYN KELLY.
FAMILY MEMBERS AND FRIENDS
DESCRIBED NEWTOWN GUNMAN
ADAM LANZA SUFFERING FROM
SOME TYPE OF MENTAL ILLNESS
OR MENTAL DISORDER WHICH
COULD HAVE CONTRIBUTED TO
THE MURDEROUS RAMPAGE.
BUT AT THIS POINT POLICE ARE
STILL TRYING TO GET THEIR
HANDS ON HIS MEDICAL
RECORDS.
A WHITE HOUSE BRIEF IS
GETTING UNDERWAY.
WE EXPECT THE ISSUE OF GUN
VIOLENCE MAY COME UP.
IT HAS IN THE PAST COUPLE
DAYS.
SUNDAY NIGHT PRESIDENT OBAMA
SAID THIS WAS THE 4th TIME
IN HIS PRESIDENCY THAT A
COMMUNITY HAS BEEN TORN
APART BY A MASS SHOOTING.
HE PROMISED TO DO EVERYTHING
IN HIS POWER TO PREVENT
ANOTHER TRAGEDY.
SEVERAL REPORTERS PRESSED
THE PRESS SECRETARY JAY
CARNEY ON THIS ISSUE, ASKING
WHY THE PRESIDENT HAS NOT
DONE MORE TO TAKE THE LEAD
ON THIS ISSUE?
>> IN THE OCTOBER
PRESIDENTIAL DEBATE THE
PRESIDENT SAID ONE OF THE
DEBATES, WEAPONS THAT WERE
DESIGNED FOR SOLDIERS IN WAR
THEATERS DON'T BELONG ON OUR
STREETS.
CAN YOU NAME ONE THING THE
PRESIDENT HAS DONE IN THE
LAST FOUR YEARS TO HELP
REMOVE WEAPONS OF WAR FROM
OUR STREETS?
>> YOU KNOW, THERE IS NO
QUESTION, JAKE, THAT THE
SCOURGE OF GUN VIOLENCE IS A
PROBLEM THAT HAS NOT
SUFFICIENTLY BEEN ADDRESSED
BECAUSE, AS WE SAW IN FEW
DOWN, WE CONTINUED TO -- NEW
TOWN, WE CONTINUE TO
TRAGEDIES THAT HURT INNOCENT
VICTIMS.
THE PRESIDENT SUPPORTS THE
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN AND
REINSTATEMENT.
>> ONE MEASURE, ONE ACT, ONE
TO REMOVE THE WEAPONS OF WAR
THAT HE TALKS ABOUT?
>> AGAIN HE SUPPORTS
LEGISLATION THAT IS DESIGNED
TO BAN SOME WEAPONS BUT AS
YOU KNOW --.
MEGYN: GUY BENSON, RADIO
TALK SHOW HOST AND POLITICAL
EDITOR AT TOWNHALL.COM.
WELCOME BACK TO THE PROGRAM.
>> THANK YOU, MEGYN.
MEGYN: THE REPORTER FROM ABC
NEWS JAKE TAPPER ASKING FOR
ONE, NAME ONE THING.
THIS IS A DEMOCRATIC
PRESIDENT, AND YOU KNOW, YOU
COULD HEAR JAY CARNEY OTHER
THAN SORT OF SPEAKING ABOUT
SOME THEORETICAL SUPPORT FOR
A RENEWED ASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN COULD NOT POINT TO ONE.
THIS IS SOMETHING HE HAS
TAKEN CONSIDERABLE FLAK FROM
THE LEFT ON BECAUSE THEY
LIKE THIS ASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN THAT WAS IN PLACE FROM
'94 TO 2004.
THE PRESIDENT HAS GIVEN A
LOT OF RHETORIC ABOUT THIS
BAN.
NOW THE QUESTIONS ARE
INCREASING ABOUT WHAT ACTION,
IF ANY HE IS WILLING TO
TAKE.
ARE THE MEDIA, ARE THEY
ASKING THE RIGHT QUESTIONS
AND WHAT ARE WE TO MAKE OF
ANSWERS WE GOT FROM
MR. CARNEY?
>> THEY'RE INTERESTING
QUESTIONS, THAT'S FOR SURE,
MEGYN AND IN TERMS OF THE
RESPONSES WE SAW FROM THE
WHITE HOUSE PRESS SECRETARY
YESTERDAY AND IN RECENT DAYS
I THINK IT REALLY DOES COME
DOWN TO TWO POINTS.
ONE IS POLITICS AND THE
OTHER IS PRACTICAL REALITY.
I THINK IT IS IMPORTANT TO
STIPULATE OF COURSE THE
PRESIDENT ABHORES THESE
TYPES OF HEINOUS AND
HORRIFIC ACTS.
WE ALL DO.
WE'RE ALL MOURNING AND JUST
HORRIFIED WHAT WE SAW.
WHEN THE PRESIDENT SPOKE
ESPECIALLY IN THE IMMEDIATE
AFTERMATH HE SORT OF HAD TO
COMPOSE HIMSELF.
A FATHER OF TWO YOUNG GIRLS.
THIS IS SOMETHING THAT THE
NATION COMES TOGETHER TO
MOURN OVER BUT AT THE END OF
THE DAY HE IS STILL THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES AND POLITICS IS
SOMETHING THAT INVOLVES
SOMETHING PRIORITIZING AND
ACTIONS SPEAK LOUDER THAN
WORDS.
JAY CARNEY IN A LATER CLIP
YOU DIDN'T PLAY, TO RANK THE
PRIORITIES.
IS THIS A TOP PRIORITY?
BIEL NOT TRY TO RANK THOSE
PRIORITIES.
THE FACT IS WE'VE SEEN THE
PRESIDENT GO FULL-COURT
PRESS ON STIMULUS, OBAMACARE,
NOW TAX HIKES.
THEY HAVE TO SORT OF DRAW
SOME LINES IN THE SAND AND
PICK THEIR SPOTS AND IT
APPEARS THIS IS NOT
SOMETHING THAT IS TRUTH BE
TOLD AT THE VERY TOP OF
THEIR LIST.
MEGYN: SOME IN THE WAKE OF
THE TRAGEDY WE SAW ON FRIDAY
AND NOT JUST THAT ONE BUT
THE ONES WE'VE SEEN IN
RECENT WEEKS, HAVE DECIDED
TO TAKE AIM AT FOLKS ON THE
RIGHT WHO DO NOT SUPPORT A
RENEWED ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN.
WHO BELIEVE IN MORE ROBUST
SECOND AMENDMENT GUN RIGHTS.
AND TAKE ISSUE WITH THEIR
POSITION.
YOU KNOW SAYING SOMEHOW THEY
HAD A HAND IN THIS.
SOMEHOW THEY SHOULD FEEL
RESPONSIBLE FOR WHAT
HAPPENED.
>> YEAH.
MEGYN: BUT THE PRESIDENT
APPEARS TO BE ON THE SAME
PAGE IN TERMS OF ACTIONS
WITH THOSE VERY PEOPLE.
HE RAN FOR OFFICE HE SAID HE
WAS GOING TO SUPPORT, HE WAS
GOING TO PRESS FOR AN
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN.
YOU SAW JAKE TAPPER TRYING
TO GET AT, WELL, WHAT
SPECIFICALLY HAS HE DONE?
NAME ONE THING HE HAS DONE?
BECAUSE EVEN THE LEFT HAS
BEEN SAYING SINCE HE TOOK
OFFICE WHERE IS THE
LEADERSHIP BEEN ON THAT?
>> YEAH.
I THINK SOME OF THE
FINGERPOINTING THAT YOU
DESCRIBE, MEGYN, IS REALLY
UNFORTUNATE.
SOME OF THE PEOPLE WHO ARE
CLAMORING LOUDEST FOR
SO-CALLED NATIONAL
CONVERSATION ABOUT GUNS AND
BY THE WAY I THINK IT SHOULD
REALLY INCLUDE MENTAL
ILLNESS AND A FEW OTHER
FACTORS HERE BUT IF WE WANT
TO HAVE A NATIONAL
CONVERSATION POINTING A
FINGER TRYING TO INDICT HALF
THE COUNTRY YOU SOMEHOW ARE
COSTICLY RESPONSIBLE FOR
STUFF LIKE THIS IS VERY
UNCONSTRUCTIVE WAY TO BEGIN
THAT CONVERSATION.
MEGYN: IT IS A GOOD WAY TO
ALIENATE YOUR ADVERSARY,
YOUR ADVERSARY WHO MAY COME
OVER TO YOUR SIDE.
WHEN THEY START TO COME OVER
TO YOUR SIDE YOU SHOULDN'T
RIDICULE THEM AND BLAME
THEM.
YOU SAID SAY, WELCOME OVER?
>> WHEN IT COMES TO WHAT THE
PRESIDENT IS PRIORITIZING
HERE, LOOK AT PUBLIC OPINION
POLLING LAST 40 YEARS,
ESPECIALLY THE LAST COUPLE
YEARS THE PERCENTAGE OF
PUBLIC SUPPORTS BROAD BASED
FAR-REACHING GUN CONTROL IS
AT AN ALL-TIME LOW.
MEANWHILE GUN OWNERSHIP IS
ALL-TIME HIGH AND VIOLENT
CRIME IS DOWN.
MEGYN: THAT IS TRUE.
EVEN RECENT PEW POLL SHOWED
MORE PEOPLE FAVOR, MORE
ROBUST GUN RIGHTS THAN THEY
DO CONSTRICTIONS ON GUN
RIGHTS.
HOWEVER, THE PEOPLE WHO ARE
IN THE GUN CONTROL CAMP SAY,
IT WOULD HELP IF WE HAD A
LEADER WHO WOULD GIVE US A
FULL-THROATED ADVOCACY OF
WHY A GUN, MORE GUN
RESTRICTIONS WOULD HELP.
>> SURE.
AND I THINK, MEGYN, BY AND
LARGE THE PRESIDENT'S
REPUTATION AS A PRAGMATIST
IN MY VIEW IS VASTLY
OVERSTATED BUT I DO WONDER
IN THIS PARTICULAR CASE
MAYBE IS THERE SOME
PRAGMATISM FROM THE
WHITE HOUSE?
WE HEARD FROM THE PRESIDENT
AND JAY CARNEY THE WORD
COMPLEX A LOT.
THIS A COMPLEX PROBLEM.
I WHOLEHEARTEDLY AGREE.
PEOPLE SAY WE HAVE TO DO
SOMETHING.
I UNDERSTAND THAT IMPULSE.
SEEING SLAUGHTERED,
DEFENSELESS CHILDREN.
HOW CAN YOU NOT HAVE A HUMAN
REACTION THAT WE HAVE TO DO
SOMETHING BUT THE STANDARD
AND THE THRESHOLD FOR ACTION
HAS TO INVOLVE EMPIRICAL
EVIDENCE AND I WONDER IF THE
WHITE HOUSE REALIZES, ALL
THESE GUN LAWS TALKED ABOUT
WOULD HAVE SINGLE ONE OF
THEM ACTUALLY PREVENTED THIS
TRAGEDY?
IF YOU LOOK AT IT CLEAR EYED,
WHICH IS DIFFICULT TO DO AT
THIS POINT IN TIME THE
ANSWER IS NO.
THAT IS TOUGH REALITY TO
SORT OF GRAPPLE WITH.
MEGYN: BECAUSE WE WANT
SOMETHING TO BLAME THAT WE
CAN DO SOMETHING ABOUT.
>> RIGHT.
THE FEEL, THE FEELING OF
DOING SOMETHING.
MEGYN: MENTAL SITUATION NOW.
BUT HIS MOTHER DID OWN THOSE
GUNS LEGALLY.
JUST SEEMS LIKE IF YOU PUT
EVERYTHING ON THE TABLE, PUT
EVERYTHING ON THE TABLE AS
YOU SAY.
GUN CONTROL, LET'S LOOK INTO
IT.
MENTAL HEALTH, LET'S LOOK
INTO IT.
VIDEOGAMES, WHATEVER IT IS.
THERE CAN'T BE INSTANT
JUDGMENT, OH, THEY RAISED
GUN CONTROL, THEY RAISED
VIDEOGAMES, OH, THEY RAISED
MENTAL HEALTH.
PUT IT ON THE TABLE TO HAVE
A HONEST DISCUSSION ABOUT IT
AND LET'S HAVE BOTH SIDES
REPRESENTED SO WE CAN HEAR
WHAT THE AS YOU SAY THE
EMPIRICAL FACTS ARE AND NOT
JUST SPIN FROM PEOPLE THAT
HAVE AN AGENDA.
GUY, THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU, MEGYN.
MEGYN: AS THE NEWTOWN
SHOOTING BLOSSOMS INTO A
NATIONAL DEBATE ON GUN
CONTROL BOTH SIDES ARE
BRINGING UPJOHN HINCKLEY'S
SAGS NATION ATTEMPT ON
PRESIDENT REAGAN AND
PRESIDENT REAGAN'S POSITION
ON GUNS AFTER THAT HAPPEN.
TODAY MICHAEL REAGAN
EXPLAINS, WELL HE EXPLORES
LONG-HELD MYTHS ABOUT HIS
FATHER'S STAND IN MUST-SEE
INTERVIEW.
THIS IS THE FIRST WE HEARD
FROM HIM SINCE WHAT HAPPENED
ON FRIDAY.
WE'LL TALK TO A MAN WHO
KNOWS ALL TOO WELL THE
DANGERS OF GUN VIOLENCE BUT
WHAT THE SOLUTIONS ARE, AS
YOU KNOW, THAT'S STILL A
QUESTION.
>>> AS LAWMAKERS FOCUS ON
LEGISLATION AFTER NEWTOWN
WE'RE HEARING NEW
HEARTWRENCHING STORIES OF
SOME OF THE PEOPLE WHO
HELPED SURVIVORS IN MOMENTS
AFTER THE ATTACK INCLUDING
THE SMALLEST CHILDREN.
ON FRIDAY MORNING GENE ROSEN
WALKED UP TO HIS HOUSE AND
DISCOVERED A GROUP OF
6-YEAR-OLDS PATIENTLY
STANDING ON HIS DRIVEWAY
NEAR THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
IT WASN'T UNTIL HE BROUGHT
THEM INSIDE.
COMFORTED THEM, GIVING SOME
OF HIS GRANDCHILDREN'S
STUFFED ANIMALS AND JUICE HE
LEARNED EXACTLY WHAT THEY
HAD BEEN THROUGH.
TODAY GENE ROSEN JOINS US
LIVE TO EXPLAIN WHAT THOSE
CHILDREN TOLD HIM AND WHY HE
SAYS THESE YOUNG SURVIVORS
TAUGHT HIM ABOUT THE TRUE
MEANING OF STRENGTH IN THE
FACE OF OVERWHELMING
TRAGEDY.
DON'T MISS THAT.
THAT IS COMING UP IN A BIT.
>>> WELLING RIGHT --
DEVELOPING RIGHT NOW ON
CAPITOL HILL, A FIERCE BACK
AND FORTH BETWEEN THE
PRESIDENT AND THE SPEAKER OF
THE HOUSE BETWEEN A POSSIBLE
PLAN TO AVOID BILLIONS IN
TAX HIKES AND SPENDING CUTS.
IT AT ONE POINT LOOKED LIKE
A DEAL MIGHT BE CLOSE.
RIGHT NOW WE'RE HEARING
THERE ARE SOME PROBLEMS.
CAMPAIGN CARL CAMERON CHIEF
POLITICAL CORRESPONDENT FROM
WASHINGTON.
>> Reporter: SHOCKER
PROBLEMS IN WASHINGTON, HEY,
MEGYN.
THERE ARE PROPOSALS GOING
BACK AND FORTH FROM EITHER
END OF PENNSYLVANIA AVENUE.
SPEAKER BOEHNER AND
REPUBLICANS AND PRESIDENT
AND THE WHITE HOUSE.
BOEHNER SAYS NEGOTIATIONS
STILL CONTINUE.
THERE IS LOT OF
COMMUNICATION STILL OPEN.
HE OFFERED UP WHAT HE SAID
WAS THE B PLAN, THAT WOULD
BE IN PLACE IF THERE IS NO
ABILITY TO AVOID GOING OVER
THE FISCAL CLIFF AND THUS
SEEING AFTER THE FIRST OF
THE YEAR MASSIVE SPENDING
CUTS AND HUGE TAX INCREASES
THAT A LOT OF PEOPLE WOULD
THROW THE COUNTRY BACK INTO
RECESSION.
BOEHNER'S B PLAN IS IGNORE
THE SPENDING COME PLONT OF
THE FISCAL CLIFF PROBLEM AND
FOCUSING ON TAX CUTS.
WITH THE BELIEF RAISING
TAXES ON STRUGGLING ECONOMY
LIKE THIS WOULD BE
DEVASTATING.
HE OFFERED UP THAT PLAN.
THIS WOULD BE NOT A
REPLACEMENT OR COUNTEROFFER
FOR THE BIG DEAL, BUT JUST
IN CASE THEY COULDN'T GET
ONE.
WATCH.
>> SO AT THE SAME TIME THAT
WE'RE GOING TO CONTINUE TO
TALK WITH THE PRESIDENT
WE'RE GOING TO ALSO MOVE
PLAN B.
I THINK WE ALL KNOW THAT
EVERY INCOME TAX FILER IN
AMERICA IS GOING TO PAY A
HIGHER RATES COME JANUARY
THE 1st UNLESS CONGRESS
ACTS.
SO I BELIEVE IT'S IMPORTANT
THAT WE PROTECT AS MANY
AMERICAN TAXPAYERS AS WE
CAN.
AND OUR PLAN B WOULD PROTECT
AMERICAN TAXPAYERS WHO MAKE
A MILLION DOLLARS OR LESS.
>> Reporter: SO IN ESSENCE
THE BUSH TAX CUTS WOULD BE
EXTENDED LEAVING TAX RATES
AS THEY ARE FOR EVERYBODY
THAT MAKES UNDER A MILLION
DOLLARS.
IT TOOK A NANOSECOND FOR THE
WHITE HOUSE TO JUMP ALL OVER
IT.
JAY CARNEY SAID HE, MEANING
THE PRESIDENT IS NOT WILLING
TO ACCEPT A DEAL THAT
DOESN'T ASK ENOUGH OF THE
VERY WEALTHIEST IN TAXES AND
INCITY SHIFTS THE BURDEN TO
MID.
IT DOES LITTLE TO ADDRESS
OUR FISCAL CHALLENGES WITH
ZERO SPENDING CUTS.
WHIFL PRESIDENT REPUBLICAN
ARGUMENT ALL ALONG THE
DEMOCRATS HAVE NOT BEEN
SERIOUS ABOUT DEALING WITH
SERIOUS SPENDING CUTS AND
THEY'RE THE ONES WHO ARE NOT
COMING TO THE TABLE.
THERE WAS A MEETING THIS
MORNING BETWEEN BOEHNER AND
REPUBLICANS OUTLINING THIS.
THERE WILL BE ANOTHER ONE AT
5:00 TO TALK ABOUT THE
IMPLEMENTATION AND VOTE ON
IT.
THEY WOULD LIKE THE PLAN B
TO BE ON THE HOUSE FLOOR AS
SOON AS THURSDAY.
MEGYN?
MEGYN: CARL CAMERON, THANK
YOU.
NEW REPORTS OF A POSSIBLE
CRIMINAL INVESTIGATION INTO
THE FILM ON THE DEATH OF
USAMA BIN LADEN.
WE'LL LOOK WHY THE MOVIE,
ZERO DARK 30, IS SPARKING A
NEW DEBATE WHETHER THE
ADMINISTRATION USED TORTURE
TO TRACK DOWN BIN LADEN AND
AS WELL ANOTHER DEBATE ON
WHY ONE TOP OFFICIAL AT THE
PENTAGON IS NOW SUSPECTED OF
SPILLING STATE SECRETS TO
HOLLYWOOD PRODUCERS.
>>> PLUS AN NBC NEWS
REPORTER IS TELLING A
FRIGHTENING STORY OF CAPTURE
AND TORTURE AFTER HE MANAGED
TO GET FREE FROM A GROUP OF
SYRIAN REBELS EARLIER TODAY.
SEE WHAT HAPPENED WHEN YOU
HEAR FROM THAT REPORTER
TELLING HIS STORY.
>>> AND THE NEXT BIG DRAMA
IN AMERICA'S HEALTH CARE
UPHEAVAL AS WE HEAR ONLY 15
STATES AGREED TO PROVIDE
COVERAGE TO THE UNINSURED.
WE'LL DEBATE WHETHER THE
FEDS ARE UP TO THE CHALLENGE,
A CHALLENGE THEY APPARENTLY
NEVER PLANNED FOR.
>> BUT WE HAVE TO PASS THE
BILL SO THE THAT YOU CAN
FIND OUT WHAT IS IN IT.
AWAY FROM THE FOG OF THE
CONTROVERSY.
HI. I'M HENRY WINKLER.
AND I'M HERE TO TELL HOMEOWNERS
THAT ARE 62 AND OLDER
ABOUT A GREAT WAY
TO LIVE A BETTER RETIREMENT.
IT'S CALLED A REVERSE MORTGAGE.
[ Male Announcer ]
CALL RIGHT NOW
TO RECEIVE YOUR FREE
DVD AND BOOKLET
WITH NO
OBLIGATION.
IT ANSWERS QUESTIONS LIKE
HOW A REVERSE MORTGAGE WORKS,
HOW MUCH YOU QUALIFY FOR,
THE WAYS TO RECEIVE YOUR MONEY,
AND MORE.
PLUS, WHEN
YOU CALL NOW,
YOU'LL GET THIS MAGNIFIER
WITH L.E.D. LIGHT
ABSOLUTELY FREE.
WHEN YOU CALL THE EXPERTS
AT One Reverse Mortgage TODAY,
YOU'LL LEARN THE BENEFITS
OF A GOVERNMENT-INSURED
REVERSE MORTGAGE.
IT WILL ELIMINATE
YOUR MONTHLY MORTGAGE PAYMENTS
AND GIVE YOU TAX-FREE CASH
FROM THE EQUITY IN YOUR HOME.
AND HERE'S THE BEST PART --
YOU STILL OWN YOUR HOME.
TAKE CONTROL
OF YOUR RETIREMENT TODAY.
♪
>> CAN I BE HONEST WITH YOU?
I AM BAD NEWS.
I'M NOT YOUR FRIEND.
I'M NOT GOING TO HELP YOU.
I'M GOING TO BREAK YOU.
ANY QUESTIONS?
MEGYN: THAT IS JUST PART OF
A SCENE FROM THE
CONTROVERSIAL FILM ON THE
HUNT FOR USAMA BIN LADEN
THAT IS SPARKING A GROWING
DEBATE ON THE
ADMINISTRATION'S POSITION ON
TORTURE.
ONE OF THE TOP DEMOCRATS IN
WASHINGTON NOW SAYS
FILM-MAKERS OF "ZERO DARK
THIRTY", QUOTE, MADE UP THE
SCENE OF ENHANCED
INTERROGATIONS.
THAT MAY OR MAY NOT HAVE LED
TO THE TERROR LEADER'S
DOORSTEP.
BUT AS FILM-MAKERS SWEAR
THEY GOT THEIR INFORMATION
STRAIGHT FROM THE CIA, WE
ARE ALSO GETTING BREAKING
NEWS TODAY ON A POSSIBLE
CRIMINAL INVESTIGATION INTO
WHETHER SOMEONE MAY HAVE
SPILLED SOME SENSITIVE
INTELLIGENCE TO HOLLYWOOD
DIRECTORS.
WE HAVE THE CEO OF CONCERNED
VETERANS FOR AMERICA AND
WITH ME NOW.
PETE, LET'S START WITH THE
LATEST NEWS AND THAT IS
THERE APPARENTLY HAS BEEN A
PENTAGON INVESTIGATION INTO
WHO, IF ANY, WAS LEAKING TO
THE FOLKS BEHIND THIS FILM,
"ZERO DARK THIRTY", WHICH IS
ABOUT HOW WE GOT BIN LADEN.
THOSE PENTAGON INVESTIGATORS
REPORTEDLY CONCLUDED THAT
THIS SENIOR DEFENSE
DEPARTMENT OFFICIAL, MICHAEL
VICKERS WHO IS MENTIONED AS
POSSIBLE CANDIDATE TO
SUCCEED PETRAEUS AT THE CIA,
LEAKED RESTRICTED
INFORMATION TO THE MAKERS OF
THIS FILM AND, AND THAT'S,
THAT PENTAGON INVESTIGATORS
ARE CONCLUDING THAT AND
REFERRED THE CASE TO THE
DOJ.
>> YEAH.
MEGYN: VICKERS AND OTHERS
BEHIND HIM SAY IF HE DID IT,
HE DID IT AT SOMEBODY ELSE'S
DIRECTION.
DON'T POINT THE FINGER AT
VICKERS.
MY FAKE WADE ON THIS, AND --
TAKEAWAY ON THIS AND YOU PUT
IT INTO PERSPECTIVE,
SOMEBODY LEAKED SOMETHING
THEY SHOULDN'T HAVE LEAKED
TO THE FILM-MAKERS OF THIS
MOVIE.
>> YEAH.
WE HAVE UNSURFACED SOLID
EVIDENCE I BELIEVE WHAT WAS
CHARGED BACK IN AUGUST 2011,
WHEN REPRESENTATIVE PETER
KING PRESSED THIS ISSUE FOR
THIS INVESTIGATION.
IT APPEARS MEMBER OF SEAL
TEAM SIX NAME WAS RELEASED
TO THE HOLLYWOOD PRODUCERS.
THE NAME OF A CURRENTLY
SERVING SEAL TEAM SIX
COMMANDER.
DOESN'T SOUND HE WAS ON THE
RAID TO BIN LADEN BUT WAS
ABLE TO PROVIDE FIRST-HAND
ACCOUNTS ABOUT IT.
VICKERS TALKS ABOUT A COUPLE
QUOTES PULLED OUT ABOUT IT.
SOUNDS LIKE ALMOST CASUAL.
I DON'T THINK SOMEONE LIKE
VICKERS IS LOOKING TO GIVE
OUT NATIONAL SECURITY
INFORMATION TO HOLLYWOOD
PRODUCERS.
LIKE HEAR IS THE NAME OF A
SEAL YOU COULD TALK TO GIVE
YOU INSIDE INFORMATION.
THAT IS BIG NO, NO.
I UNDERSTAND MAKING FILMS
ARE ACCURATE.
WE WANT FILMS TO ACCURATELY
DEPICT HISTORY BUT IF WE'RE
GIVING OUT CLASSIFIED
INFORMATION IN THE PROCESS,
THAT IS NO GOOD.
MEGYN: THEY WILL LOOK INTO
THAT AND WE'LL SEE WHAT IF
ANYTHING COMES FROM IT.
BUT AT THE SAME TIME, THERE
IS THIS EMERGING QUESTION
ABOUT WHETHER THE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION IS GUILTY OF
THE SAME TACTICS THEY WERE
CRITICAL OF THE BUSH
ADMINISTRATION ON, NAMELY,
WATERBOARDING AND ENHANCED
INTERROGATION.
THIS MOVIE SEEMS TO SUGGEST
THAT WE DID ENGAGE IN
WATERBOARDING IN ORDER TO
GET THE IDENTITY OF THAT
COURIER WHO WAS BRINGING
THINGS INTO THE BIN LADEN
COMPOUND AND WHO DID PROVE
TO BE CRITICAL IN OUR
ABILITY TO LOCATE BIN LADEN.
>> YEAH, IT'S A
HE SAID/SHE SAID BECAUSE NO
ONE ACTUALLY HAS SEEN THE
FILM AND ONLY A SMALL SUBSET
HAVE CHARACTERIZED IT.
WHAT IT COMES DOWN TO THE
LEFT DOESN'T WANT TO ADMIT
THAT ENHANCED INTERROGATION
WORKS IN ANY WAY OR IN ANY
WAY LED TO THE CAPTURE OF
BIN LADEN.
THEY'RE LOCKED IN ON THAT.
SO THE FILM HAS TO
MISREPRESENT HISTORY IF IT
LEADS A, TO B, TO C, TO
BIN LADEN.
THOSE WHO UNDERSTAND
ENHANCED INTERROGATION
TECHNIQUES, WHETHER THEY'RE
RIGHT OR WRONG, THEY WORK.
AFTER 9/11 THEY WERE USED ON
A CERTAIN SUBSET, SMALL
SEGMENT OF DETAINEES TO
GATHER INFORMATION, SOME OF
WHICH MAY HAVE LED TO THE
CAPTURE OF BIN LADEN.
HOW THE FILM DEPICTS IT I'M
NOT QUITE SURE.
I HAVEN'T SEEN IT BUT YOU
CAN'T DENY THE FACT THAT
ENHANCED TEAR GAGS --
INTERROGATION GOOD OR BAD
LED TO MORE INTELLIGENCE AND
LED TO HIGH LEVEL CAPTURES.
MEGYN: THERE IS APPARENTLY
EXTENDED INTERROGATION SCENE
SHOWS A TERRORIST BEING
DESCRIBED AS COMPOSITE
CHARACTER, BEING
WATERBOARDED, DEPRIVED OF
SLEEP, CHAINED TO THE
CEILING, BEING BEATEN
SEVERELY AND FORCED INTO A
SMALL BOX.
DIANNE FEINSTEIN WHO CHAIRS
THE SENATE INTEL COMMITTEE
SAYS LOOK, WE DIDN'T DO ANY
WATERBOARDING WHEN WE
INTERROGATED BIN LADEN'S
COURIER AT LEAST.
THEN THE DIRECTOR, CATHERINE
BIGELOW COMES OUT AND SAYS
THE FILM IS BASED FULLY ON
FIRST-HAND ACCOUNTS OF THE
INVESTIGATION.
BIGELOW SEEMS TO BE SAYING
YOU DID TORTURE.
WE GOT THIS DIRECTLY FROM
OFFICIALS IN THE KNOW.
AND DIANNE FEINSTEIN AND
OTHERS ARE SUGGESTING, NO,
WE DIDN'T.
WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF IT?
>> WOULDN'T HAVE BEEN
WATERBOARDING OF THE COURIER.
WATERBOARDING OF A SELECT
FEW, KHALID SHEIKH MOHAMMED
AND FEW OTHERS AFTER 9/11 WE
IDENTIFIED WE WERE USING
THIS TECHNIQUE.
I THINK THERE IS A LOT OF
HE SAID/SHE SAID.
THERE IS THREE-YEAR
INVESTIGATION ONGOING WHICH
WILL BE THE DEFINITIVE
REPORT ON ENHANCED
INTERROGATION TECHNIQUES AND
EFFICACY.
SHE HAS ACCESS TO THAT.
DID WAR BOARDING LEAD TO THE
NAME OF THE CURRIER? MAYBE
NOT.
DID WATERBOARDING LEAD TO
OTHER INFORMATION THAT LED
TO THE COURIER?
POSSIBLY.
A TO B TO C IS GOOD
INTELLIGENCE WORK AND IT
COULD HAVE STARTED WITH GOOD
ENHANCED INTERROGATION
TECHNIQUES.
WE DON'T KNOW AT THIS POINT.
MEGYN: IS THE WATERBOARDING
PORTRAYED IN THE FILM
SUPPOSEDLY TAKEN PLACE UNDER
PRESIDENT OBAMA?
>> I DON'T THINK SO.
MEGYN: THERE IS DEBATE
WHETHER THE INTEL THAT WAS
GLEANED IN ANY PRIOR
WATERBOARDING PROVED
INTEGRAL TO NABBING
BIN LADEN.
>> THAT'S WHAT IT SEEMS BUT
THE MOVIE SEEMS TO SORT OF
SUGGEST THAT PRESIDENT OBAMA
KNEW ABOUT IT BECAUSE IT
GOES STRAIGHT FROM THE
INTERROGATION TO A SPEECH
FROM PRESIDENT OBAMA.
SO THERE'S, THERE'S SOME
HOLLYWOOD TIMELINISM IN
THERE THAT CONNECTS THE
PRESIDENT TO THOSE
PARTICULAR TECHNIQUES WHICH
HE HAS SAID FROM DAY ONE HE
STOPPED USING.
YOU HAVE TO SAY PROBABLY A
LITTLE HOLLYWOOD FLAIR AND
MIGHT HELP US ALL TO GO SEE
THE MOVIE ON JANUARY 11.
MEGYN: WE'LL SEE WHAT THE
DOJ DOES WITH MR. VICKERS.
THANK YOU SO MUCH, PETE.
>> THANK YOU, MEGYN.
MEGYN: THE PRESIDENT'S
OVERHAUL OF HEALTH CARE WAS
BASED ON CRITICAL
IMPLEMENTATION OF HEALTH
CARE EXCHANGES BUT STATES
SAY NO
[ loud party sounds ]
HI,
I'M Ensure Clear...
Clear, HUH?
I'M NOT JUICE OR FANCY WATER.
I'VE GOTINE GRAMS OF PROTEIN.
THAT'S THREE TIMES MORE THAN ME!
[ Female Announcer ]
Ensure Clear.
NINE GRAMS PROTEIN. ZERO FAT.
IN BLUEBERRY/POMEGRANATE
AND PEACH.
MEGYN: THERE IS AN IRONIC
TWIST TO THE SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT THAT TOUCHED OFF
A NEW GUN DEBATE.
WE ARE GETTING REPORTS THAT
GUN SALES ARE SOARING IN A
NUMBER OF STATES OVER THE
LAST FEW DAYS.
TRACE GALLAGHER HAS DETAILS
FROM OUR WEST COAST
NEWSROOM.
TRACE?
>> Reporter: MEGYN, IF YOU
GO BACK IT COLUMBINE, AURORA,
AND VIRGINIA TECH, EVERY
TIME THERE IS MASS SHOOTING
IN THIS COUNTRY, GUN SALES
DRAMATICALLY RISE.
EXPERTS SAY THAT IS FOR A
COUPLE REASONS.
ONE, FOR PERSONAL SAFETY.
AND TWO, THE PEOPLE BELIEVE
THE GOVERNMENT WILL BAN
CERTAIN TYPES OF WEAPONS
LIKE ASSAULT RIFLES.
HERE ARE TWO DIFFERENT VIEWS
ON THE ISSUE.
LISTEN.
>> AS FAR AS ASSAULT WEAPONS,
I DON'T THINK IT IS
NECESSARY.
PISTOL WORKS JUST AS FINE.
>> INSTANCES LIKE THIS
CREATE A KNEE-JERK REACTION.
THEY HAVE GOT TO LOOK AT
SOMETHING TO VILIFY.
SO MUCH EASIER TO VILIFY A
GUN THAN IT IS A SYSTEM THAT
IT HAS HOLES IN IT THAT
NEEDS TO IT BE FIXED.
>> Reporter: THE DAY AFTER
THE CONNECTICUT SHOOTING THE
COLORADO BUREAU OF
INVESTIGATION HAD 4154
REQUESTS FOR BACKGROUND
CHECKS ON GUN BUYERS.
THEY SIMPLY COULD NOT
PROCESS THEM THAT FAST.
AND THEY ARE STILL TODAY
TRYING TO CLEAR UP THE
BACKLOG.
THE NATIONAL INSTANT
CRIMINAL BACKGROUND CHECK IS
EXPERIENCING SIMILAR NUMBERS
TO COLORADO.
IN INDIANA, GUN SALES ARE
SEEING AN UPTICK IN
SEMIAUTOMATIC SPORT RIFLES
AS WELL AS HANDGUNS,
AMMUNITION AND EVEN
HOLSTERS.
A GUN SHOP IN RACINE,
WISCONSIN, ALL OF LAST YEAR
THEY SOLD THREE AR-15
ASSAULT RIFLES LIKE THE ONE
ADAM LANZA USED IN
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL.
LAST WEEK THEY SOLD FIVE.
THEY MIGHT HAVE SOLD MORE
BUT THEY SOLD OUT OF THE
FIVE THEY HAD.
KEEP IN MIND PRESIDENT
CLINTON PUT A BAN ON ASSAULT
RIFLES BACK IN 1994.
THAT BAN EXPIRED IN 2004.
CLEARLY MANY ARE CONVINCED
ANOTHER BAN WILL SOON BE IN
PLACE.
MEGYN: TRACE, THANK YOU.
WELL A BIG NUMBER OF STATES
ARE REDUCING TO -- REFUSING
TO SET UP THE HEALTH
EXCHANGES A CRITICAL PART OF
PRESIDENT'S HEALTH CARE
OVERHAUL.
BOTTOM LINE, WHAT ARE NAME
OF AIRLINE THINGS YOU GO AND
LOOK LIKE, NO, NO NOT
BOARDING PASS.
ORBITS, THOSE LITTLE THINGS
WE GO ON AND SAY, I WANT THE
BEST FLIGHT FOR THE BEST
DOLLAR.
THAT IS HOW THESE INSURANCE
EXCHANGES ARE SUPPOSED TO
WORK.
GO ONLINE, I'M THIS AGE AND
I WANT THE BEST INSURANCE
POLICY THESE STATES WERE
SUPPOSED TO SET UP THESE
THINGS.
NOW THE VAST MAJORITY OF
THEM SAID, NO WE'RE NOT
GOING TO DO IT.
SO WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
THE FEDS HAVE TO DO IT?
DO YOU PAY FOR THAT?
HOW IS THAT GOING TO WORK?
WE'LL TALK ABOUT IT RIGHT
AFTER THE BREAK.
>>> A U.S. VETERAN NOW BEING
HELD IN A NOTORIOUS MEXICAN
PRISON CHAINED TO HIS BED.
HIS PARENTS JOIN ME LIVE
ABOUT THE FIGHT TO FREE
THEIR SON.
>> I WAS SHATTERED, I WAS
JUST SHATTERED.
HE LOOKED SO HOPELESS.
AS A MOTHER TO SEE YOUR
CHILD LOOK LIKE THAT AND NOT
BEING ABLE TO HELP HIM IS
JUST, IT FEELS OBSCENE
MEGYN: WE ARE GETTING NEW
INFORMATION ON THE CAPTURE OF
RICHARD ENGEL FROM NBC NEWS.
HE'S DESCRIBING HOW THE REBELS
KEPT HIM AND HIS TEAM TIDE AND
BEAT UP.
THEY MADE THEM CHOOSE WHICH ONE
WOULD BE SHOT FIRST AND THEN
HELD MOCK SHOOTINGS.
WE'LL HA THIS IN
A LIVE REPORT IN MOMENT.
THE PRESIDENT'S HEALTHCARE
OVERHAIL WAS BASED ON A CRITICAL
NET WORK OF STATE EXCHANGES.
AN ONLINE SITE THAT WOULD HELP
YOU FIGURE OUT WHAT PLAN YOU
MIGHT BE AVAILABLE FOR AND HOW
MUCH IT WOULD COST YOU.
ALL THAT TAKES BODIES AND
RESOURCES.
THE STATES WERE SUPPOSED TO DO
IT.
BUT THE MAJORITY OF STATE ARE
SAYING THEY ARE NOT GOING TO DO
IT OR AT A MINIMUM THEY WANT TO
PARTNER WITH THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT TO DO IT.
SO THERE IS A LOT MORE WORK HERE
FOR UNCLE SAM THAN THEY
ANTICIPATED WHEN THEY PASSED
THIS BILL AND WHEN THEY FUNDED
THIS BILL.
WHERE DOES THAT LEAVE US TODAY?
LESS MYANMAR SHAWL AND LARS
LARSON.
THE FEDS ARE SAYING WE ARE
GOING TO SUBSIDIZE HEALTH
INSURANCE FOR THE PEOPLE WHO
CAN'T AFFORD IT.
IT'S LIKE AN ORBITZ.
YOU GO ONLINE.
MEGYN KELLY NEW YORK, HOW OLD
ARE YOU -- YOU CAN LIKE THE UP.
MEDICAL BACKGROUND.
RACE.
THEY ASK YOU ALL YOUR BACKGROUND
THINGS.
YOU PLUG IN YOUR INFORMATION AND
SOMEBODY HAS TO SET UP THE
ONLINE THING AND BE ON THE
RECEIVING END TO PROCESS THE
INFO SUCH AS THEY CAN RETURN
BACK TO YOU.
IF YOU QUALIFY FOR THE GOLD PLAN
AT THIS RATE.
THIS IS THE AMOUNT OF SUBSIDY
YOU WOULD GET AND THIS IS HOW
YOU GO ABOUT GETTING IT.
25 STATES HAVE DEFAULT OUGHT
STATES ENTIRELY AND ANOTHER 7
SAID WE WANT AT A MINIMUM TO
PARTNER WITH THE FEDS.
SO YOU HAVE GOT 32 STATES SAYING
THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT WILL BE
ENTIRELY OR PARTIALLY
RESPONSIBLE.
THEY DIDN'T PLAN ON THAT.
HOW ARE THEY GOING TO GET THIS
DONE?
>> I THINK THE MONEY IS ACTUALLY
THERE.
WHAT I HEAR IS JOB CREATION
WHETHER IT'S ON A STATE OR
FEDERAL LEVEL.
MEGYN: THERE WERE REPORTS THEY
WERE TALKING ABOUT ROBBING PETER
TO PAY PAUL, TAKING IT OUT OF A
DIFFERENT BUDGET OF THE FEDS AND
USING THAT MONEY.
IT COULD BE A BILLION PLUS, AND
USING THAT MONEY TO SET THIS UP.
>> THE MONEY THEY DID PLAN ON
WAS MONEY THEY WOULD APPROPRIATE
TO EACH STATE.
I'M ASSUMING HERE NOW.
THAT THEY WOULD NOT BE
APPROPRIATING AS MUCH TO A STATE
THAT'S GOING TO SAY THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT HAS TO HANDLE THE
SETUP OF THAT HEALTHCARE ORBITZ
ENTIRELY.
I'M ALSO HEARING PEOPLE SAID ON
THE RIGHT LIKE MY BUDDY LARS WHO
WE'LL HEAR FROM IN A MINUTE, I
CAN'T WAIT -- WHAT I HEAR IS WE
WANT LESS FEDERAL GOVERNMENT,
BUT YOU GUYS HANDLE THIS.
WE WANT POWER TO GO TO THE
STATES AND THE STATES SAYING WE
CAN'T HANDLE THIS.
COME ON.
MEGYN: THE STATES WEREN'T THE
ONES WHO PASSED OBAMA-CARE.
THIS WAS A FEDERAL EFFORT AND
THEY WERE TOLD BY THE FEDS YOU
ARE DOING IT.
>> THIS THING IS A MESS.
>> A GUY NAME MITT ROMNEY SAID
THE REASON IT WORKED IN
MASSACHUSETTS AND THE REASON
WHEN HE WAS GOVERNOR HE SIGNED
OFF ON IT AND WANTED IT WAS
BECAUSE IT WAS A STATE-RUN
PROGRAM.
THIS IS AT LEAST A PORTION OF
THE POWER AND THE IMPLEMENTATION
GIVE TO THE VARIOUS STATES.
>> THIS THING HAS BEEN A
DISASTER.
BUT YOU HIT ON ONE OF THE
ANSWERS.
IF ORBITZ SET THIS UP, IF
PRIVATE INDUSTRY HAD DONE IT.
IT WOULD HAVE BEEN DONE BETTER.
THEY NEVER WOULD HAVE SET UP A
SEPARATE ORBITZ FOR EVERY STATE
IN AMERICA.
AN AWFUL LOT OF AMERICANS, THE
MAJORITY OF AMERICAN STATES
OPPOSE THIS PLAN.
FURTHER, THE EXCHANGES ARE
RIDICULOUS BECAUSE THEY WILL
ONLY DEAL WITH PEOPLE WHO OBTAIN
THEIR HEALTH INSURANCE NOT FROM
THE GOVERNMENT, AND NOT FROM
THEIR EMPLOYER WHICH IS THE
MAJORITY OF THE REST OF THE
PEOPLE NOT COVERED BY MEDAID
AND MEDICARE.
THEY HAVE TO BUY IT INDIVIDUALLY
AND IT WILL GO TO THESE
EXCHANGES.
BUT IN MOST EXCHANGES YOU CAN
BITE EXPENSIVE AIRLINE TICKET
OTHER INEXPENSIVE AIRLINE
TICKET.
THIS WON'T GIVE YOU THAT CHOICE
BECAUSE OBAMA CARE MANDATES THE
MINIMUM PLAN IS A CADILLAC PLAN.
SO HOW MUCH CHOICE ARE YOU GOING
TO HAVE WHEN THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT SAYS THIS IS THE
LEAST YOU CAN OFFER WHICH IS
EVERYTHING INTO THE PLAN KIND OF
OFFER.
MEGYN: THAT SPEAKS TO WHETHER
OBAMA-CARE IS GOOD OR BAD PORE
INADEQUATE OR ADEQUATE.
THAT SHIP HAS SAILED.
THE LAW PASSED.
NOW IT'S A QUESTION OF WHETHER
THIS WILL BE ADEQUATELY
IMPLEMENTED BY THE FEDS WHEN
THEY WERE NOT PLANNING TO BE --
I LIKE WHAT YOU SAID, HEALTHCARE
ORBITZ.
THEY WERE NOT PLANNING TO RUN
HEALTHCARE ORBITZ.
>> THEY WERE FUNDING IT.
AND LET ME POINT SOMETHING ELSE
OUT.
MEGYN: FUNDING IT IS DIFFERENT
THAN HAVING THE BODIES TO SET UP
THE WEB SITE AND DO THE
PROCESSING, THIS AGE, THIS KIND
OF A SMOKER, THIS CHALLENGE
TAKE.
THIS FAMILY HISTORY.
THAT TAKES PEOPLE AND RESOURCES.
>> IT THERE WAS ALREADY
SOMETHING FOR OTHER KINDS OF
INSURANCE CALLED QUOTE SMITH
WHERE YOU COULD FIND QUOTES ON
OTHER KINDS OF INSURANCE.
IF PRIVATE INDUSTRY HAD DONE
THIS WE WOULD HAVE SEEN
COMPETITION.
I DON'T MEAN JUST IN THE KIND OF
PLAN OFFERED.
YOU WOULD HAVE EVEN THE PRIVATE
CITY STEP TO THE FORE.
THEY OFFER PRODUCTS THAT ARE A,
COMPLICATED, AND B EXPENSIVE.
WHEN PEOPLE HAVE CHOICES.
THOSE KINDS OF THINGS COULD HAVE
BEEN DONE BY PRIVATE INDUSTRY.
BUT THERE IS ANOTHER WRINKLE
THAT ONLY AN ALBANY LAW GRADUATE
WOULD BE ABLE TO FIGURE OUT.
IT PROVIDED IF YOU GO TO A STATE
EXCHANGE AND NEED THE SUBSIDY
FROM THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT THE
LAW ALLOWS FOR A CHECK TO BE
CUT.
IF IT'S THROUGH THE FEDERAL
EXCHANGE THE LAW APPEARS TO HAVE
A FLAW TONIGHT THAT DOES NOT
ALLOW THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT TO
CUT CHECKS.
THAT A REAL PROBLEM.
MEGYN: THERE IS ANOTHER
CHALLENGE THAT HAS TO DO WITH
WHETHER THEY CAN TAX -- YOU KNOW
HOW YOU ARE SUPPOSED TO PAY A
PEN FAT YOU DON'T INSURE YOUR
EMPLOYEES?
THESE CORPORATIONS THAT IF THEY
HAVE MORE THAN 50 EMPLOYEES THEY
HAVE TO PAY A PENALTY.
NOW THERE IS A LEGAL CHALLENGE
BUBBLING UP ABOUT WHETHER THAT
PROVISION OF THE LAW CAN BE
SUSTAINED IF THE EXCHANGES ARE
RUN BY THE FEDS VERSUS THE
STATES.
I DON'T WANT TO GET THAT DEEP
INTO IT BECAUSE YOUR HEAD WILL
HE CAN MOWED.
BUT THIS WRINKLE OPENED UP A NEW
POSSIBLE CHALLENGE TO THE CORE
OF THE LAW.
BUT THE QUESTION I HAVE FOR DAYS
WHERE ARE THEY GOING TO GET THE
MONEY?
WHERE ARE THEY GOING TO GET THAT
EXTRA MONEY?
IS THE COST OF THIS LAW
BALLOONING IN A WAY THAT WAS NOT
ANTICIPATED BY SOME?
>> I DON'T BELIEVE SO FOR
SEVERAL REASONS.
ONE, I DO FEEL THE MONEY THAT
WOULD BE APPROPRIATED SAY HERE
IN CALIFORNIA AND WE SAY YOU
GUYS HANDLE IT.
THEY WON'T GIVE US THE MONEY FOR
THAT BECAUSE WE WON'T BE
HANDLING THAT.
I DON'T SEAT ISSUE WITH
FINANCES.
LARS, TO YOUR POINT ABOUT THE
INSURANCE COMPANIES.
ALL THOSE BIG CEOs AT AETNA
AND BLUE CROSS.
THEY HAVE THE POWER BEFORE THIS
WAS PASSED AND THEY STILL HAVE
THE TOUR LOWER THEIR RATES.
SO IT AMUSES ME WHEN THEY SAY
OBAMA-CARE IS GOING TO INCREASE
RATES THAT THEY HAVE 100%
CONTROL OVER SITTING AT THE
HEADS OF THEIR PRIVATE
COMPANIES.
>> TO HER POINT.
ACTUARIES TELL YOU WHAT THOSE
POLICYS HAVE TO COST.
THE MARKETPLACE AND THE REAL
COST OF DOING IT.
YOU WILL SEE AN AWFUL LOT OF
STATES.
MEGYN: DID YOU USE THE WORD
ACTUARIES?
DON'T EVER DO THAT AGAIN.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
A NEW DRAMA IN THE EFFORT TOO
SAVE A U.S. MARINE CHAINED TO
HIS PRISON BED.
THE BIGGEST ASSIST THEY MAY HAVE
GOTTEN FROM AN UNLIKELY ALLY
INSIDE MEXICO.
WE'LL HEAR FIRSTHAND ABOUT A
NEWS CREW TAKEN HOSTAGE IN
SYRIA.
MY DOCTOR TOLD ME CALCIUM
IS EFFICIENTLY ABSORBED IN SMALL
CONTINUOUS AMOUNTS.
Citracal Slow Release
CONTINUOUSLY RELEASES CALCIUM
PLUS D
WITH EFFICIENT ABSORPTION
IN ONE DAILY DOSE.
Citracal Slow Release.
MEGYN: FOX NEWS ALERT ON THE
FATE OF A U.S. MARINE LOCKED UP
IN MEXICO FOR MONTHS.
WE GOT A PICTURE OF HIM LOCKED
UP INSIDE OF ONE OF MEXICO'S
MOST DANGEROUS PRISONS.
HIS NAME IS JOHN HAMMER.
SHIRTLESS AND CHAINED TO A BED.
WE ARE TOLD IT WAS SENT TO HIS
FAMILY FROM AN ANONYMOUS MEXICAN
E-MAIL ACCOUNT.
HE FACES CHARGES FOR CARRYING
THIS GUN, A FAMILY HEIRLOOM,
OVER THE BORDER.
BREAKING EARLIER TODAY A BIG
GROUP OF BUSINESSMEN INSIDE THE
NORTHERN MEXICO PRESSED THEIR
OWN GOVERNMENT FOR HIS RELEASE
BECAUSE THEY ARE WORRIED ABOUT
AMERICAN TOURISTS AND MAKING
MEXICO ATTRACTIVE TO US.
A LOT OF AMERICANS ARE UNHAPPY
THE WAY OUR MARINE IS BEING
TREATED BY OUR SO-CALLED FRIEND
MEXICO.
JOINING US, THE PARENTS OF JOHN
HAMMER.
A LOT OF AMERICANS ARE OUTRAGED
BY WHAT'S HAPPENING TO YOUR SON.
IT SEEMS SOMEWHAT CLEAR HE MAY
HAVE VIOLATED SOME MEXICAN LAW
ABOUT BRINGING THE GUN IN.
IT MAY HAVE BEEN TOO SHORT OR
TOO LONG BY AN INCH.
WHY DIDN'T THEY JUST SAY WHEN HE
STOPPED AND SHOWED THEM THE GUN.
SAY CAN'T TAKE IT, DOESN'T
COMPLY WITH OUR LAWS, TURN
AROUND AND GO BACK HOME.
>> I DON'T KNOW FOR A FACT.
I CAN ONLY SPECULATE THEY WERE
HOPING THAT HE WOULD OFFER THEM
A BRIBE.
THAT WAS OUR -- THAT'S WHAT A
LOT OF PEOPLE HAVE TOLD US.
IF HE HAD OFFERED THEM A BRIBE
HE MIGHT HAVE BEEN ABLE TO AVOID
THIS.
MEGYN: THAT COMPORTS WITH YOUR
EXPERIENCE.
I KNOW YOU GOT A CALL FROM THIS
MEXICAN PRISON AND TELL US WHAT
THEY DEMANDED.
>> THEY DEMANDED MONEY.
FOR HIS SAFETY AND THEY SAID
THEY WERE GOING TO KILL HIM IF
WE DIDN'T SEND IT IMMEDIATELY.
YOU KNOW, AT THE BORDER CROSSING
IT COULD HAVE BEEN THAT THEY
IDENTIFIED HIM AS AN AMERICAN
VET AND WANTED TO STICK IT TO
HIM ALSO, YOU KNOW, OTHER THAN
JUST MONEY.
MEGYN: HE'S 27 YEARS OLD.
HE DID MULTIPLE TOURS IN IRAQ
AND AFGHANISTAN.
HE WAS SUFFERING FROM POST
TRAUMATIC STRESS DISORDER.
HE WAS GOING TO MEXICO TO DO
SOME HUNTING WITH HIS FRIEND.
THIS IS HOW HE BURNS OFF STRESS.
THE MEXICAN AUTHORITIES SAID IT
DOESN'T QUITE COMPORT WITH OUR
LAWS SO YOU AND YOUR FAMILY
HEIRLOOM ARE IN VIOLATION OF OUR
LAWS.
HE'S BEEN SITTING THERE FOR FOUR
MONTHS.
THIS PICTURE WE HAVE OF HIM
CHAINED TO THE BED LIKE A DOG --
ORIGINALLY THEY HAD HIM IN THE
GENERAL POPULATION OF THIS
PRISON THAT'S FULL OF MEXICAN
DRUG CARTEL MEMBERS.
>> THAT RIGHT.
THAT'S WHEN WE BEGAN RECEIVING
THE EXTORTION CALLS.
THE MOVE FROM THE HIM THAT THE
CONSULATE WAS ABLE TO ARRANGE TO
THIS@SER AREA WAS TO TRY AND
CIRCUMVENT THAT HAPPENING AGAIN.
MEGYN: NOW I UNDERSTAND BASED ON
SOME PHONE CALLS THAT WERE MADE
BY AMERICAN OFFICIALS, THEY
REMOVED THE CHAIN FROM HIS LEG
AT LEAST?
>> YES, I BELIEVE AS OF LAST
WEDNESDAY THE CHAIN WAS REMOVED.
MEGYN: I KNOW THIS IS THE FIRST
TIME YOU HAVE SEEN A PICTURE OF
HIM.
HOW DID YOU FEEL WHEN YOU SAW
IT?
>> SICK.
YOU KNOW -- IT'S LIKE A
"NATIONAL GEOGRAPHIC" SHOW THAT
YOU WATCHED EXCEPT IT'S YOUR
SON.
IT'S INCONCEIVABLE.
MEGYN: JOHN, WE WERE TOLD
CONSULAR OFFICERS HAVE VISITED
YOUR SON FOUR TIMES IN PRISON.
THE STATE DEPARTMENT MADE SURE
HIS RIGHTS ARE PROTECTED AND
THERE IS ONLY SO MUCH THEY CAN
DO.
THIS WILL PLAY OUT IN THE
MEXICAN LEGAL SYSTEM THE SAME
WAY IT WOULD PLAY OUT IN THE
U.S. SYSTEM IF A MEXICAN GOT
CAUGHT TRYING TO BRING AN
ILLEGAL FIREARM INTO OUR
COUNTRY.
>> IN THE LAST FEW DAYS --
ESPECIALLY THE MEXICAN STATE
DEPARTMENT, BUT OUR STATE
DEPARTMENT, TOO, HAS BEEN
PROTECTING THEMSELVES INSTEAD OF
PROTECTING JOHN.
MEGYN: THE THING THAT AMAZES ME
WHEN WE LOOK AT YOUR SON'S CASE.
THIS IS AN ALLY.
THIS ISN'T LIKE WHEN THE HIKERS
CROSS OVER INTO THE BORDER OF
IRAN AND NEXT THING YOU KNOW
THEY ARE HELD THERE.
THAT'S A FRIEND OF OURS, MEXICO.
AND WE SPENT $1.BILLION ON AN
ASSISTANCE PROGRAM TO MEXICO
THAT IS NOW FOCUSED ON HELPING
THEM REVAMP' THEIR LEGAL SYSTEM,
THEIR COURTS, THEIR BRING SNS,
THEIR PROSECUTIONS.
DO IT AMAZE YOU THAT GIVEN THAT
$1.9 BILLION, WE CAN'T MAKE A
PHONE CALL, DON'T BE RIDICULOUS.
HE DECLARED IT.
YOU SHOULD HAVE JUST TURNED HIM
AROUND.
RELEASE OUR MARINE.
>> I TOTALLY DON'T UNDERSTAND
IT.
BUT IN ONE CONVERSATION I HAD
WITH JOHNNY HE SAID TO ME, MOM,
THEY HATE US.
HE SAID THEY HATE -- THE HATRED
FOR AMERICANS IN THIS PLACE IS
UNBELIEVABLE.
AND THAT HAS HAUNTED ME.
I'M NOT SURE WHAT THAT'S ABOUT.
MEGYN: FROM REPORTS, IN
PARTICULAR THIS GROUP OF
CARTEL-AFFILIATED GROUPS DOWN
THERE.
NOT ALL THE MEXICAN PEOPLE FEEL
THAT WAY.
BUT HIS DEFENSE ATTORNEY SAID
SOMETHING SIMILAR.
THEY ARE HOPING TO MAKE AN
EXAMPLE OF HIM AND THEIR POWER
OVER THIS AMERICAN MARINE.
JOHN, YOU KNOW YOUR SON.
HE HAS BEEN THROUGH A LOT
ALREADY AND PAID A PRICE.
PTSD IS SOMETHING A LOT OF OUR
VETS SUFFER WITH.
EXPLAIN YOUR WORRIES ABOUT HIS
MENTAL STATE.
>> HE'S BEEN HYPER STRESSED
ALONE FOR MONTHS NOW.
SO THAT'S A CONCERN NOW.
HYPER VIGILANT, AND THAT IS PART
OF THE THING THEY IDENTIFY FROM
THE EFFECTS OF WAR THAT THEY TRY
TO TREAT AND GIVE TOOLS TO
TREAT.
WE ARE HOPING WE GET HIM BACK
TODAY, TOMORROW, AS SOON AS
POSSIBLE SO THAT WE CAN GET WITH
HIM AND START TO HELP HIM.
MEGYN: HIS NEXT COURT APPEARANCE
ISN'T UNTIL JANUARY.
LEGAL EXPERTS SAY NOTHING IS
LIKELY TO HAPPEN BEFORE THEN.
LET MANY HOPE THEY ARE WRONG.
THEY STILL HAVE A 2% CONVICTION
RATE FOR MOST CRIMES.
SO WE HAVE THAT GOING FOR US.
I KNOW HE'S FACING UP TO 12
YEARS.
>> LET MANY HOPE IT'S FOR
AMERICAN AS WELL.
THANK YOU FOR BEING HERE.
NBC NEWS CORRESPONDENT RICHARD
ENGEL AND HIS CREW ARE OUT OF
SYRIA AFTER A HARROWING ORDEAL.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
MEGYN: NEW DETAILS ON AN NBC
REPORTER CAPTURED IN SYRIA.
HE'S DESCRIBING HOW THE REBELS
KEPT HIS TEAM BLINDFOLD AND TIED
UP.
HE SAYS THEY WERE NOT PHYSICALLY
BEATEN BUT SUFFERED A LOT OF
PSYCHOLOGICAL TORTURE INCLUDING
THREATS OF BEING KILLED.
>> Reporter: RICHARD ENGEL
SAYS THEY WERE ESCORTED BY A
GROUP OF REBELS IN AN AREA THEY
THOUGHT WAS CONTROLLED BY REBELS
WHEN ARMED GUNMEN SYMPATHETIC TO
THE GOVERNMENT JUMPED OUT,
HEAVILY ARMED, THEY GRABBED THEM
AND PUT THEM IN A CONTAINER
TRUCK.
HE SAYS HIS CAP TOWARDS WERE
SUPPORTING THE SYRIAN GOVERNMENT
AND EXECUTED ONE OF THE REBEL
ESCORTS ON THE SPOT.
HE SAYS THEY WERE TAKEN TO A
SERIES OF SAFE HOUSE AND THEY
WERE BLINDFOLD AND BOUND.
>> WE WEREN'T BEATEN AND
TORTURED.
THERE WAS PSYCHOLOGICAL TORTURE.
THEY MADE US CHOOSE WHICH ONE
WOULD BE SHOT FIRST.
THERE WERE MOCK SHOOTINGS.
THEY THREATENED TO TO SHOOT GAZI
FIRST.
THE.
>> Reporter: HE SAYS THEY WERE
BEING MOVED AGAIN TO WHAT HE
THINKS WAS A HEZBOLLAH
STRONGHOLD.
THEY UNEXPECTEDLY CAME ACROSS A
TREBLE CHECKPOINT.
A GUNFIGHT BROKE OUT.
TWO OF HIS CABER TOES WERE
KILLED, HE AND HIS CREW WERE
RESCUED BY THE REBELS.
>> THE LAST FIVE DAYS HAVE BEEN
DIFFICULT.
WE ARE HAPPY TO BE BACK IN
TURKEY.
WE LOVE BEING HERE.
WE LOVE THIS COUNTRY.
WE APPRECIATE ALL THE HELP.
>> Reporter: RICHARD ENGEL HAS
BEEN NBC'S CHIEF FOREIGN AFFAIRS
CORRESPONDENT SINCE 2008.
HE SPEAKS FLUENT EA -- HE SPEAK.
MEGYN: TRACE, THANK YOU.
AS THE NEWTOWN SHOOTINGS TURNS
INTO A NATIONAL DEBATE ON GUN
CONTROL.
BOTH SIDES ARE TALKING ABOUT THE
ASSASSINATION ATTEMPT ON RONALD
REAGAN.
BUT TODAY MICHAEL REAGAN
DISCUSSES SOME LONG-HELD MYTHS.
A MAN FACING A POSSIBILITY OF
JAIL TIME WHEN HE TRIES TO MAKE
A CITIZEN'S ARREST ON A COP.
>> WHO THE HELL DO YOU THINK YOU
ARE.
PULL OVER.
[ loud party sounds ]
HI,
I'M Ensure Clear...
Clear, HUH?
I'M NOT JUICE OR FANCY WATER.
I'VE GOTINE GRAMS OF PROTEIN.
THAT'S THREE TIMES MORE THAN ME!
[ Female Announcer ]
Ensure Clear.
NINE GRAMS PROTEIN. ZERO FAT.
IN BLUEBERRY/POMEGRANATE
AND PEACH.
MEGYN: A DISTURBING REVELATION
FROM INVESTIGATORS IN THE SANDY
HOOK MASSACRE.
THEY SAY THERE IS NO INDICATION
ADAM LANZA WAS TAKING MEDICATION
FOR ANY HEALTH ISSUES.
LAND ZAPS PARENTS TOLD FRIENDS
HE SUFFERED FROM ASPERGER'S
SYNDROME, TODAY CONSIDERED
AUTISM.
DURING THEIR SEARCH OF THE HOME
THAT LANZA SHARED WITH HIS
MOTHER NANCY THEY FOUND NO
EVIDENCE OF PRESCRIPTION DRUGS
AND THEY SAY HE LOOK GREAT PAINS
TO DESTROY HIS HARD DRIVE ON HIS
COMPUTER.
A SIGN HE MAY HAVE PLANNED THIS
RAMPAGE WELL IN ADVANCE.
RICK LEVENTHAL JOINS US LIVE
FROM NEWTOWN.
>> Reporter: THE LATEST
DEVELOPMENT IS ANOTHER FUNERAL
PROCESSION PASSING BEHIND US.
WE BELIEVE THIS IS FOR JESSICA
REKOS.
IT IS FOCUSING ON WHAT IF ANY
MEDICATIONS ADAM LANZA MIGHT
HAVE BEEN TAKING.
THAT WAS THE QUESTION WE ALL
ASKED IN THE MOMENT AFTER THIS
ATTACK.
MENTAL HEALTH EXPERTS THINK
CERTAIN MEDICATIONS CAN
CONTRIBUTE TO ERRATIC BEHAVIOR.
AUTHORITIES ARE USING SEARCH
WARRANTS TO OBTAIN MEDICAL
RECORDS.
THE WORD OF ADAM'S ASPERGER'S
COMES FROM STATEMENT HIS MOM
MADE IN DIVORCE DOCUMENT.
ONE KEY PIECE OF EVIDENCE MAY
HAVE BEEN SEVERELY DAMAGED, THE
COMPUTER HARD DRIVE TO ADAM'S
COMPUTER.
SOURCES SAY SMASHED THAT HARD
DRIVE BEFORE HEADING OUT ON HIS
SHOOTING SPREE.
WE HAVE BEEN SEEING FUNERALS
TODAY.
THAT'S WHERE EARLIER THIS
MORNING 6-YEAR-OLD JAMES
MATTIOLI WAS REMEMBERED.
HE BEAT HIS DUE DATE BY FOUR
WEEKS BECAUSE HE WAS HUNGRY.
THE SERVICES BEGAN FOR JESSICA
REKOS.
THE FOURTH 6-YEAR-OLD TO BE
BURIED THE LAST COUPLE DAYS.
EVEN AS THE MOURNERS ARE PAYING
THEIR RESPECTS.
NEWTOWN REOPENED FIVE OF THE
SEVEN SCHOOLS IN THIS SCHOOL
DISTRICT.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY IS STILL A
CRIME SCENE AND MAY NEVER
REOPEN.
ANOTHER SCHOOL THAT WAS SUPPOSED
TO REOPEN REMAINED CLOSED
BECAUSE OF AN UNSPECIFIED
THREAT.
MEGYN: WE HEARD YESTERDAY ABOUT
HOW THERE HAS BEEN SO MANY
PEOPLE WHO WANTED TO VOLUNTEER
TO HELP THOSE FAMILIES AND HELP
THAT COMMUNITY.
AND EVEN UNDERTAKERS AND FOLKS
IN THE FUNERAL BUSINESS KNOWING
THAT THIS -- I'M TOLD ONLY ONE
MAJOR FUNERAL OPERATION IN TOWN
HAVE RUSHED TO HELP IT, TO HELP
THE FAMILIES TO TRY TO GET
EVERYBODY THROUGH THIS AS
QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE.
SATISFACTORILY ONE FUNERAL HOME
MAY NOT HAVE BEEN ABLE TO HANDLE
THE VOLUME HERE.
>> Reporter: THEY HAD TO HIRE
A COUPLE DOZEN MORE PEOPLE TO
HANDLE THIS TRAGIC NUMBER OF
VICTIM THAT NEED TO BE CARED FOR
AND LAID TO REST.
WE HEARD COMPELLING STORIES OF
PEOPLE REACHING OUT.
THE GOVERNOR'S OFFICE IS TRYING
TO SET UP A CHARITY THAT
EVERYONE CAN GIVE TO.
ONE CASE WE HEARD ABOUT WAS A
COFFEE SHOP IN TOWN GOT A CALL
FROM SOMEONE IN CALIFORNIA WHO
WANTED TO BUY 100 CUPS OF COFFEE
FOR MOURNERS.
THEY SAID THEY COULDN'T AFFORD
BREAKFAST FOR EVERYONE BUT THEY
COULD BUY THEM A COUP OF COFFEE.
MEGYN: CHILDREN ARE BEING HELPED
IN THE HEALING PROCESS BY MAN'S
BEST FRIEND.
SEVEN DOGS TRAINED TO COMFORT
DISASTER SURVIVORS PUT SMILES ON
THE FACES OF CHILDREN FOR THE
FIRST TIME SINCE FRIDAY.
THE DOGS OFFER A SENSE OF
SECURITY THAT OTHERS CAN
PROVIDE.
THERE IS SOMETHING STRESS
RELIEVING AND COMFORTING ABOUT
PEGHT AN ANIMAL AND HAVING THE
LOVER AN ANIMAL EVEN FIT MANY
ONLY TEMPORARY.
GREAT IDEA.
WE HAVE BREAK NEWS OUT OF
WASHINGTON OVER A PLAN TO HEAD
OFF A TAX HIKE AND A BUNCH OF
SPENDING CUTS.
AT ONE POINT IT LOOKED LIKE BOTH
SIDES WERE CLOSE TO A DEAL.
TODAY NOT EXACTLY BUT WE'LL SEE.
THE WHITE HOUSE REJECTED HOUSE
SPEAK I ARE JOHN BOEHNER --
HOUSE SPEAKER DOWNBOEHNER'S
BACKUP PROPOSAL.
LESS THAN AN HOUR AGO JAY CARNEY
SAYS THE PRESIDENT HAS BEEN
TRYING TO COMPROMISE.
>> THE FACT THAT HE'S WILLING TO
COMPROMISE AND HAVE RATES GO UP
ON THOSE MAKING $400,000 AND
ABOVE AS OPPOSED TO $250,000 AND
ABOVE DEMONSTRATES HIS GOOD
FAITH EFFORT TO REACH A COME
PREMICE AND STILL HAVE A PACKAGE
THAT'S BALANCED AND ASKS THE
WEALTHIEST TO PAY MORE.
MEGYN: MELISSA FRANCES JOINS US.
WHAT ARE THEY ARGUING OVER?
IT SEEMS LIKE THEY ARE GETTING
CLOSE.
>> Reporter: IT SEEMS LIKE IT.
THERE IS PLAN "A" AND PLAN "B."
PLAN "A" IS THE NEGOTIATION
GOING ON BETWEEN SPEAKER BARON
AND THE PRESIDENT.
THEY ARE GETTING CLOSE WITH THE
PRESIDENT SAYING WE'LL RAISE
TAXES ON PEOPLE WHO MAKE
$400,000.
HE BUMMED IT UP TO $400,000.
BOEHNER WAS AT A MILLION.
THERE ARE THOUGHTS THEY COULD
SETTLE AT $500,000.
THEN PLAN "B," THE BACKUP PLAN
SAYING WE TAKE THIS BILL FROM
THE SENATE.
WE TALK ABOUT IT IN THE HOUSE,
WE SEND IT BACK.
THAT STARTED AT $250,000.
THAT ONE SPEAKER BOEHNER GOING
IN WITH THIS OFFER OF $MILLION.
THEY MIGHT SETTLE IN THE MIDDLE.
ALL OF THESE PLANS TOGETHER CUT
SPENDING BY A TRILLION.
SO THEY ARE KIND OF -- IT'S
ALMOST THIS ONE FOR ONE RATIO.
THE GOOD OLD DAYS WE ARE TALK
ABOUT CUTTING SPENDING BY 3-1.
THAT SEEMS TO BE GONE.
IT HAS A FEELING LIKE WE ARE
GETTING CLOSER.
THERE ARE A COUPLE FLIES IN THE
OINTMENT.
THERE ARE ALL THE HOUSE
REPUBLICANS AND CONSERVATIVES,
SAYING I DON'T KNOW WHO SPEAKER
BOEHNER IS SPEAKING FOR.
WE ARE NOT GOING TO VOTE FOR ANY
OF THIS.
MEGYN: HISTORICALLY WE HAVE BEEN
TOLD TAXES HAVE NEVER BEEN
RAISED WHEN THE REPUBLICANS ARE
IN CHARGE OF THE HOUSE.
THEY DON'T BELIEVE WE HAVE A
REVENUE PROBLEM, THEY BELIEVE WE
HAVE A SPENDING PROBLEM.
IF THEY DO THIS THEY WILL BE
CHANGING HISTORY.
>> Reporter: IT'S HARD TO
IMAGINE THEY WILL.
THE THEORY IS WHY WOULD YOU FEED
THE BEAST AND MAKE IT BIGGER.
WE NEED TO STARVE IT.
THIS IS THE FLY IN THE OINTMENT
FOR SPEAKER BOEHNER FOR SURE.
THERE IS A LOT OF TALK THAT HE
DOESN'T HAVE THE SUPPORT TO CUT
THESE DEALS.
BRET BAIER BROKE OUT SOME
FANTASTIC NUMBERS SAYING WE TAKE
IN $5 BILLION A DAY.
WE SPEND $11 BILLION.
NO MATTER HOW MUCH YOU RAISE
TAXES.
CAN YOU IMAGINE IF WE RAN OUR
HOUSEHOLDS LIKE THAT.
YOU MAKE $50 AND YOU GO HOME AT
NIGHT AND SHOP ONLINE AND YOU
SPEND $110 DAY AFTER DAY.
THAT'S HOW WE ARE RUNNING OUR
COUNTRY.
THE REALITY IS ALL OF THESE GOAR
YAITIONS DON'T EVEN COME CLOSE
TO SOLVING OUR PROBLEMS.
MEGYN: WE'LL LOOK BACK AT THE
RICH AND SAY WE RAISED YOUR
TAXES BY 4% TO%.
WE ARE UNREALISTIC IN THE AMOUNT
OF REVENUE WE THOUGHT WE NEEDED.
AND AT SOME POINT THEY WILL HAVE
TO TALK ABOUT SPENDING CUTS BUT
NO ONE HAS THAT CURLING.
EVEN THE REPUBLICANS ARE SAYING
LET'S FORGET THE SPENDING CUTS.
>> Reporter: IT SEEMS LIKE NO
ONE HAS TH THE COURAGE.
WE HAVE TO TURN INTO GREECE
FIRST.
DEPENDING ON WHICH OF THESE
SCENARIOS WE ARE TALKING ABOUT.
IT'S ALL NOTHING.
EVENTUALLY THEY RUN OUT OF
MONEY.
THE FED KEEPS PRINT IT.
MEGYN: IF WE ARE GOING TO BE
GREECE I WOULD LIKE A GOOD EURO.
THANK YOU.
AS THE NEWTOWN SHOOTING IGNITED
A DEBATE ON GUN CONTROL, SOME
ARE TALK ABOUT THE ASSASSINATION
ATTEMPT OF PRESIDENT REAGAN AND
HIS VIEW ON GUNS.
MICHAEL REAGAN IS HERE IN A
MUST-SEE INTERVIEW.
A MICHIGAN MAN IS HEAD TO COURT
AFTER HE DECIDED TO MAKE A
CITIZEN'S ARREST OF A POLICE
OFFICER.
HERE HE IS TRYING TO PULL THE
COP OVER.
>> I SAID SIR, YOU NEED TO WEAR
YOUR SEAT BELT.
AND IT SET ME OFF.
I WAS MAD AS HELL.
SINCE I'VE LOST WEIGHT I HAVE SO
MUCH MORE ENERGY THAN I USED TO,
WHEN I'M OUT WITH MY KIDS, MY
DAUGHTER'LIKE, "MOM, WAIT UP!"
AND I'M THINKING, "SHOULDN'T YOU
HAVE MORE ENERGY THAN ME?
YOU'RE, LIKE, EIGHT!"
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR EVERY 2 POUNDS YOU LOSE
THROUGH DIET AND EXERCISE
ALLI CAN HELP YOU LOSE
ONE MORE
BY BLOCKING SOME OF THE FAT
YOU EAT.
SIMPLE. EFFECTIVE.
ADVANTAGE: MOM.
LET'S FIGHT FAT WITH ALLI.
HAVE A HEALTHIER HOLIDAY
AT LETSFIGHTHOLIDAYFAT.COM.
MEGYN: DAYS AFTER THE TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT BOTH SIDES IN THE
GUN DEBATE ARE TALKING ABOUT THE
RULES GOVERNING OUR WEAPONS.
BOTH SIDES ARE INVOKED THE
MEMORIES OF PRESIDENT REAGAN WHO
WAS HIMSELF SHOT BY A CRAZED
GUNMAN.
WE'LL GET TO TRACE GALLAGHER WHO
WILL SET THE SCENE FOR US.
>> REPORTER: IT WAS 69 DAYS
AFTER HE TOOK OFFICE AS
PRESIDENT.
HE WAS WALK OUT OF A SPEECH AT
THE HILTON IN D.C.
YOU CANNOT FORGET WHEN HE RAISED
HIS HANDS, SECONDS LATER JOHN
HINCKLEY OPENED FIRE.
ONE OF THE BULLETS ENTERED
PRESIDENT REAGAN'S CHEST.
PUNCTURING A LUNG.
LODGING ONE INCH FROM HIS HEART.
HE WAS PUSHED INTO THE LIMO BY A
SECRET SERVICE AGENT WHO WAS
ALSO TAKING A BULLET TO THE
CHEST.
HE WALKED INTO THE HOSPITAL
UNDER HIS OWN POWER.
JOKING TO THE DOCTORS HOPING
THEY WERE ALL REPUBLICANS.
PRESS SECRETARY JAMES BRADY WAS
SHOT IN THE HEAD.
HE WAS PERMANENTLY DISABLED.
HE WENT ON TO CHAMPION GUN
CONTROL.
BUT EVEN AFTER JOHN LENNON WAS
SHOT AND HE WAS SHOT, PRESIDENT
REAGAN OPPOSED GUN CONTROL.
THEN 10 YEARS LATER HE CAME OUT
IN A LETTER SUPPORTING THE BRADY
ACT.
KEEP IN MIND THE BRADY CENTER
HAS RECENTLY COME OUT SAYING
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S FIRST YEAR,
THEY GAVE HIM 7 Fs FOR HIS
EFFORTS ON GUN CONTROL.
MEGYN: WHERE WOULD PRESIDENT
REAGAN LIKELY STAND ON THIS
TODAY?
HERE TO SPEAK ABOUT IT, HIS SON,
MICHAEL REAGAN.
HE'S A POLITICAL CONSULTANT AND
CHAIRMAN OF THE REAGAN GROUP.
YOUR DAD HAD A UNIQUE
PERSPECTIVE ON THIS.
AS GOVERNOR OF CALIFORNIA RIGHT
AFTER HE WAS SHOT AND 10 YEARS
AFTER HE WAS SHOT.
TAKE US THROUGH IT.
>> WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT THE DAY
WAS SHOT.
I SAID TO MIKE, HOW COULD YOU
LET THIS HAPPEN WITH ALL THE
SECRET SERVICE PROTECTION MY
FATHER HAD.
HE SAID WE CAN TRAIN TO PROTECT
THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES BUT WE'LL NEVER BE ABLE
TO PROTEC PRO -- NEVER BE ABLE N
ENOUGH TO PROTECT AGAINST THE
CRAZIES.
MY FATHER WAS DEEPLY AFFECTED.
NOT BY THE BULLET IN HIS CHEST.
MY FATHER WAS DEEPLY AFFECTED BY
THE BULLETS THAT ENTERED OTHER
PEOPLE, WITH BULLETS THAT WERE
MEANT FOR HIM.
WITH MY FATHER FLYING BACK ON
AIR ONE.
MY FATHER COUNTED OUT THE NUMBER
9.
I SAID WHAT'S IMPORTANT ABOUT
THE NUMBER 9.
HE SAID IN 9 MORE MONTHS I'LL NO
LONGER BE PRESIDENT.
I SAID WHY IS THAT IMPORTANT TO
YOU?
HE SAID I CAN GO BACK TO CHURCH.
HE SAID EVERY SINCE I LOOKED OUT
THE WINDOW OF THAT CAR THAT DAY
AND SAW PEOPLE LAYING IN THEIR
OWN BLOOD IN BULLETS MEANT FOR
ME.
I DIDN'T WANT TO PUT PEOPLE IN
HARM'S WAY IF I ENTERED A ROOM.
SO I HAVE NOT BEEN GOING TO
CHURCH ON A REGULAR BASIS AND
THAT'S WHAT I'M LOOKING FORWARD
TO.
GROWING UP MY FATHER OWNED WHAT
WOULD BE DEEMED AN ASSAULT
RIFLE.
A .22 CALIBER SEMIAUTOMATIC AND
15 LONG RIFLES.
HE GAVE ME A GUN WHEN I WAS 10
YEARS OLD.
HE BELIEVED IN GUN
RESPONSIBILITY WHICH IS WHAT HE
TRULY BELIEVED IN.
GROWING UP AS A FATHER, TEACHING
A RESPONSIBLE RESPONSIBILITY OF
THE RIFLE.
AND WHAT HAVE YOU.
1991 IS AN INTERESTING YEAR IN
MY FATHER'S LIFE.
LET ME JUMP IN FOR ONE SECOND.
RIGHT AFTER AWAS SHOT IN 1981 HE
CAME OUT AND SAID HE HADN'T
CHANGED HIS POSITION ON GUN
CONTROL.
HE SAID HE OPPOSED GUN CONTROL
AND SAID HE WAS DISTURBED WITH
ALL THE FOCUS ON GUN CONTROL AS
AN ANSWER FOR OUR PROBLEM.
10 YEARS LATER 1991 HE'S NO
LONGER IN OFFICE BUT THE BRADY
BILL IS MAKING ITS WAY THROUGH
CONGRESS AND HE WRITES AN OP-ED
THAT ADVOCATES IN FAVOR OF THAT
GUN CONTROL BILL AND SAYS LOOK,
THIS LEGISLATION -- THIS
NIGHTMARE THAT HAPPENED TO ME
MIGHT NEVER HAVE HAPPENED IF
THAT LEGISLATION, THE BRADY BILL
HAD BEEN LAW IN 1981.
>> I BELIEVE THAT WAS THE
10-YEAR ANNIVERSARY.
IT HAD QUITE AN EFFECT ON MY
FATHER FOR THE FAMILY.
I REMEMBER BEING ON THE RADIO AT
THE TIME.
THAT WAS MORE OF A BLESSING TO
JAMES BRADY WHAT HE HAD GONE
THROUGH SINCE 1981, THE LIFE HE
HAD TO LIVE AND WHAT HAVE YOU.
BUT MY FATHER BELIEVED TRULY
THAT TAKING GUNS AWAY FROM
LAW-ABIDING CITIZENS WAS NOT THE
ANSWER TO SOLVING PROBLEMS IN
THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA.
AND YOUR STAFF AND I TALKED ON
MANY OCCASIONS IN THE LAST WEEK.
THE PROBLEM WITH MAYOR CASE OUR
BUILDING BLOCKS ARE BROKEN.
TAKING THE GUNS AWAY WHICH IS
THE END RESULT DOES NOT SOLVE
THE INHERENT PROBLEM IN AMERICA,
THE BUILDING BLOCKS, AND THE
ISSUES YOU TALKED ABOUT
YESTERDAY ON YOUR SHOW.
THERE ARE FAMILIES OUT THERE WHO
CAN'T GET HELP.
YOU CAN'T DEAL WITH A CHILD.
ONCE THEY TURN 18 THEY ARE ON
THEIR OWN.
YOU CAN'T PUT THEM AWAY.
YOU NEED A COURT ORDER FOR EVEN
72 HOURS.
WHEN YOU TALK ON YOUR SHOW ABOUT
THERE NEEDS TO BE A NATIONAL
CONVERSATION ABOUT THIS AND NOT
JUST AIM AT GUN CONTROL.
YOU ARE ABSOLUTELY CORRECT.
THAT IS NOT TRULY THE ANSWER.
GUN CONTROL WORKED IN
CONNECTICUT.
HE TRIED TO BUY A GUN TWICE AND
IT DIDN'T WORK OUT.
I HAVE BEEN LIVING THROUGH THIS
BECAUSE I HAVE A DAUGHTER
ASHLEY, 29 YEARS OLD, 5'2".
WHO DOES THAT SOUNDS LIKE.
TEACHES KINDERGARTEN.
SHE HAS BEEN SO AFFECTED BY THIS
AS SO MANY TEACHERS HAVE BEEN
AFFECTED BY THIS AND WHAT THEY
ARE LIVING WITH AND GOING
THROUGH.
WHAT WE NEED TO DO IS FIND A WAY
TO PROTECT THE CHILDREN.
PUTTING A GUARD IN EVERY SCHOOL.
THAT NEEDS TO BE DONE.
THAT'S WHERE RONALD REAGAN WOULD
BE.
HE WOULDN'T SAY LET'S HAVE GUN
CONTROL.
HE WOULD SAY LET'S PUT GUARDS AT
SCHOOL AND WORK ON REBUILDING
THE BUILDING BLOCKS OF AMERICA.
MY FATHER SAYS IT ALL STARTS AT
OUR DINNER TABLE, NOT THE
GOVERNMENT'S DINNER TABLE.
MEGYN: THERE IS A QUESTION ABOUT
WHETHER ADAM LANZA MANY MOTHER'R
WOULD HAVE HAD AT LEAST ONE OF
THESE GUNS IF THE ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN WOULD HAVE BEEN IN
PLACE.
I DON'T KNOW THE ANSWER TO THAT.
A REPORT SAYS TWO OF THE GUNS
WOULD HAVE BEEN BAND BUT THE
LONG BEGUN, THE AR-15 WOULD HAVE
BEEN.
>> IS THE DEBATE HOW MANY
CHILDREN WE ARE WILLING TO LOSE?
LOOK AT JOHN HINCKLEY.
HE HAD BASICALLY A PEA SHOOTER.
ALL THE SECRET SERVICE AT THAT
TIME AT THAT PLACE WITH THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES.
HE WAS STILL ABLE TO SHOOT FOUR
PEOPLE AND GET 6 SHOTS SOME OF
WITHOUT A SECRET SERVICE AGENT
DOING ANYTHING AT THAT POINT IN
TIME.
ARE WE GOING TO NEGOTIATE HOW
MANY LIVES?
THIS SEEMS TO BE WHERE IT'S
GOING HERE.
HOW DO YOU STOP ANYBODY FROM
DYING?
YOU PUT A GUARD AT SCHOOLS IS
WHAT YOU DO.
>> A LOT OF FOLKS, YOU DON'T
WANT TO JUST DEPRIVE THE MADMAN
OF HIS WEAPON OF CHOICE.
YOU WANT TO CONTROL THE MADMAN.
YOU WANT TO DO SOMETHING TO CURB
OR CONTROL THE DESIRE TO KILL.
THAT NUMBER ONE.
BUT I THINK THE DEBATE ABOUT GUN
CONTROL HAS COME IN ON WHEN THAT
FAILS HOW DO WE DEPRIVE HIM OF
THE ABILITY TO HURT AS MANY
PEOPLE AS WANT.
I THINK THAT'S WHERE THE
DISCUSSION ABOUT THE MAGAZINES
AND ALL THAT HAS COME IN.
I'LL GIVE YOU THE LAST WORD.
>> THERE NEED TO BE A NATIONAL
DISCUSSION.
YOU ARE RIGHT ON WHAT YOU ARE
SAYING ON FOX AND ON YOUR SHOW
AND THAT'S WHERE I WOULD LIKE TO
BE.
MEGYN: THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
BEING HERE.
ALL THE BEST TO YOU.
AS LAWMAKERS FOCUS ON
LEGISLATION AFTER NEWTOWN WE ARE
HEARING NEW HEART WRENCHING
STORIES OF SOME OF THE PEOPLE
WHO HELPED SURVIVORS IN THE
MOMENT AFTER THE ATTACK.
JEAN ROSEN DISCOVERED A GROUP OF
STUDENTS PATIENTLY STANDING IN
HIS DRIVEWAY.
IT WASN'T UNTIL HE BROUGHT THEM
INSIDE AND COMFORTED THEM WITH
JUICE THAT HE LEARNED WHAT THEY
HAD BEEN THROUGH.
[ Male Announcer ]
RESEARCH SUGGESTS CELL HEALTH
PLAYS A KEY ROLE
THROUGHOUT OUR LIVES.
One A Day Men's 50+
IS A COMPLETE MULTIVITAMIN
DESIGNED FOR MEN'S HEALTH
CONCERNS AS WE AGE.
IT HAS 7 ANTIOXIDANTS
TO SUPPORT CELL HEALTH.
One A Day Men's 50+.
FLAVOR BOOST, MEET BEEF.
IT'S SWANSON FLAVOR BOOST.
CONCENTRATED BROTH
TO ADD DELICIOUS FLAVOR
TO YOUR SKILLET DISH
IN JUST ONE STIR.
MMM!
[ Female Announcer ]
COOK, MEET COMPLIMENTS.
GET RECIPES AT FLAVORBOOST.COM.
MEGYN: AN NFL RUNNING-BACK PAYS
TRIBUTE TO THE VICTIMS OF THE
SCHOOL MASSACRE.
HE RAN FOR A 94-YARD TOUCHDOWN
AGAINST THE NEW YORK JETS, AND
ON THOSE SHOES WERE THE NAMES OF
THE VICTIMS KILLED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
HE SAYS HE WAS HEARD BROKEN BY
THE TRAGEDY AND WAS FLEERK ANY
WAY HE COULD REMEMBER THEM.
IT'S A ONE OF A KIND TRAINING
FACILITY OF COUNTER-TERRORISM
SITE THAT CANNOT BE FOUND
ANYWHERE ELSE IN THE WORLD WHERE
LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICERS LEARN
TO DEAL WITH CYBER WARFARE TO
WEAPONS OF MASS DESTRUCTION.
>> Reporter: WE HAVE
HIGH-SPEED CHASE TRAINING GOING
ON BEHIND ME.
THEY BUILT A MINIATURE WORLD.
ONE OF THE MAIN GOALS IS TO TRY
TO PUT AS MUCH REAL LIFE
PRESSURE AS POSSIBLE ON FEDERAL
RESPONDERS.
AT THE FEDERAL LAW ENFORCEMENT
TRAINING CENTER IN BRUNSWICK,
GEORGIA, THEY USE BLANK
AMMUNITION, BUT REAL ACTORS.
>> YOU CAN'T SIMULATE BEHAVIOR.
YOU HAVE TO USE PEOPLE TO I AM
SLATE BEHAVIOR.
>> Reporter:
AGENTS A YEAR COME TO THE SITE
COMPLETE WITH MOCK AIRPLANES,
BARS AND A TEST TRACK.
NO EMBANKMENTS, NO BRIDGES, NO
CONGESTION.
TERROR ATTACKS FROM THE PAST
LIKE A SARIN GAS SUBWAY ATTACKS
ARE REHEARSED ALONG WITH FUTURE
ATTACKS LIKE IMPROVISED
EXPLOSIVE DEVICES.
RESPONSE TRAINING TO ABDUCTIONS
OR ACTIVE SHOOTERS IS ONLY PART
OF THE MISSION.
>> WE CAN'T AFFORD TO JUST
RESPOND TO INCIDENTS.
WE HAVE TO PREVENT THING FROM
HAPPENING.
WE GET A SENSE FROM TALKING TO
THE INSTRUCTORS OF JUST HOW
URGENT AND IMPORTANT THEY FEEL
THEIR MISSION IS HERE IN
GEORGIA.
MEGYN: STEVE HARRIGAN.
THANK YOU.
RIGHT AFTER THIS BREAK.
ONE OF THE PEOPLE WHO HELPED THE
YOUNGEST SURVIVORS IN MOMENT
AFTER THE SANDY HOOK ATTACK.
GENE ROSEN DISCOVERED A GROUP OF
STUDENTS NEATLY SITTING IN A
SEMI CIRCLE AT THE BOTTOM OF HIS
DRIVEWAY NEAR THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
IT WASN'T UNTIL HE BROUGHT THEM
INSIDE COMFORTING THEM WITH
STUFFED ANIMALS AND JUICE THAT
HE DISCOVERED WHAT THEY HAD BEEN
THROUGH.
A MAN TRIES TO EXECUTE A
CITIZEN'S ARREST AND NOW HE'S
FACING JAIL TIME.
>> YOU ARE REQUIRE BID LAW TO
WEAR YOUR SEAT BELT.
PUT YOUR DAM SEAT BELT ON.
PULL IT OVER.
PULL YOUR VEHICLE OVER.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
RIGHT NOW.
>> HOT HELL DO YOU THINK YOU
ARE.
PULL OVER.
MEGYN: WE'RE HEARING NEW
STORIES OF STRENGTH AND
RESILLIANCE AFTER THE
TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN.
HE ONE MAN SAYS IF THERE IS
ANY STRENGTH IT LIES IN THE
BRAVE STUDENTS THAT SURVIVED
THAT DAY.
LAST FRIDAY MORNING GENE
ROSEN DISCOVERED A GROUP OF
STUDENTS IN HIS DRIVEWAY
NEAR THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
NOT UNTIL HE BROUGHT THEM
INSIDE GIVING THEM STUFFED
AN MASS AND JUICE UNTIL HE
LEARNED EXACTLY WHAT THEY
HAD JUST BEEN THROUGH.
HE WAS SO INSPIRED ABOUT THE
PERCENT VAERNS FROM THE
TRAGEDY HE IS LEARNING THE
LESSONS FROM THE YOUNG
SURVIVORS.
ONE OF HIS GREATEST HOPES IS
TO SOME DAY SEE THEM AGAIN.
GENE ROSEN JOINS US LIVE
FROM NEWTOWN.
GOD BLESS YOU FOR THE HELP
YOU PROVIDED THOSE YOUNG
CHILDREN IN SUCH A TRAUMATIC
MOMENT.
TAKE US THROUGH IT.
YOU WALK OUTSIDE THE DOOR.
YOU'RE ABOUT TO GO GET
BREAKFAST AND WHAT DID YOU
SEE AT THE END OF THE
DRIVEWAY?
>> I SAW SIX CHILDREN AT THE
END OF THE DRIVEWAY AND I
SAW A MAN SPEAKING KIND OF
HARSHLY TO THEM IN A LOUD
VOICE SAYING, IT'S GOING TO
BE ALL RIGHT, IT'S GOING TO
BE ALL RIGHT.
I THOUGHT IT WAS A SKIT OR A
PLAY OR SOME CUB SCOUTS
SCOUTS WERE REHEARSING.
THEY WERE SITTING IN A VERY
ORDERLY WAY AND I, I HAD NO
CLUE THAT ANYTHING HAD
HAPPENED.
WHEN I START GETTING CLOSER
TO THEM I COULD SEE THE
DISTRESS AND THE FEAR AND
THE DISORDER THEY HAD JUST
WITNESSED.
THEY SEEMED OUT OF BREATH.
THERE WAS A SCHOOL BUS
DRIVER WITH THEM.
AND I SAID, COME ON INSIDE.
COME ON INSIDE.
AND THEY JUST FOLLOWED ME.
MEGYN: HOW DID YOU FIRST
LEARN, IT WAS FOUR LITTLE
GIRLS AND TWO LITTLE BOYS,
THAT THEY HAD JUST RUN,
LITERALLY FROM VICTORIA
SOTO'S CLASSROOM, A TEACHER
WHO WAS KILLED IN FRONT OF
THEM?
>> I DINL LEARN ABOUT IT
UNTIL 15 MINUTES OR 20
MINUTES IN THEIR STAY AT MY
HOUSE.
I BROUGHT DOWN MY GRANDSON'S
STUFFED ANIMALS.
AND THEY PLAYED WITH THEM.
THEY DIDN'T SAY VERY MUCH.
I BROUGHT THEM SOME JUICE.
AND THEN THEY SEEMED TO BE
CALMER.
WE WENT TO A DIFFERENT ROOM.
AND THEN, IT ALL STARTED
UNFOLDING AND IT STARTED
THIS WAY.
THIS BOY SAID, WE CAN'T GO
BACK.
WE CAN'T GO BACK TO THE
SCHOOL.
WE CAN'T GO BACK.
WE DON'T HAVE A TEACHER.
AND THEY KEPT REPEATING
THAT.
I COULD NOT FATHOM WHAT THEY
WERE SAYING.
I COULD NOT TAKE IT IN WHAT
THEY WERE SAYING.
AND THEN ONE OF THEM SAID,
OUR TEACHER IS DEAD.
WE CAN'T GO BACK.
MRS. SOTO IS DEAD.
AND I THINK ONE OF THE GIRLS
SAID, THERE WAS BLOOD IN HER
MOUTH AND SHE FELL DOWN.
AND THEN SOMEHOW THEY ESCAPED.
AND MEGYN, I DON'T KNOW THE
DETAILS OF THEIR ESCAPE.
I DON'T KNOW HOW THEY ESCAPED
BUT THEY MUST HAVE RUN SOME
PORTION OF THE ROAD THAT IS
NEXT TO THE FIREHOUSE AND
WAS PICKED UP, WERE PICKED
UP BY A SCHOOL BUS DRIVER.
AND I DON'T KNOW HOW THEY
ESCAPED BUT UNTIL I SAW
VICTORIA SOTO'S NAME IN THE
CASUALTY LIST I COULD NOT
BELIEVE IT BECAUSE IT WAS
UNFATHOMABLE.
MEGYN: THEY WERE WITHIN
INCHES OF DYING THEMSELVES
AND IT WAS MOMENTS AFTER
WHEN THEY WERE IN YOUR HOME.
WHAT WAS THEIR AFFECT?
KIDS ARE SO RESILIENT AND
THEY DON'T UNDERSTAND EVIL
THE WAY WE DO AND DON'T
UNDERSTAND HORROR THE WAY WE
DO SO WHAT WAS THEIR AFFECT
WHEN THEY WERE WITH YOU?
>> THEY WERE INITIALLY KIND
OF AGITATED.
AND THEN THE STUFFED ANIMALS
SEALED TO CALM THEM DOWN.
THEN THEY TOLD THEIR STORY,
AND, IT JUST WAS SO HARD TO
BELIEVE.
AND THEN AS IF GOD HAD SENT
DOWN A LITTLE ANGEL THERE
WAS A RESPITE FROM THE
TERROR AND ONE OF THE BOYS
WHO MUST BE A VERY ASSERTIVE,
CLEVER, DIRECT BOY, HE SAID,
HE CHANGED HIS COMPOSURE AND
HE PUT UP HIS HAND AND HE
SAID, JUST SAYING, YOUR
HOUSE IS VERY SMALL.
AND I WANTED TO HOLD HIM.
AND I WANTED, I THOUGHT AT
THAT MOMENT HE HAD, HE HAD
JUST BROUGHT US OUT OF HELL
FOR JUST A MOMENT AND I WILL
NEVER FORGET THAT.
MEGYN: OH, GENE.
>> AND MY, MY, MY DESIRE IS
TO HAVE PARENTS CALL ME AND
TO REUNITE WITH THESE
CHILDREN AND TO READ TO THEM
AND TO BE WITH THEM AND TO
LOVE THEM AND TO LET THEM
KNOW THAT I'LL HELP THEM
FIND THE LIGHT BECAUSE THEY
WERE IN THE DARKNESS.
THAT'S MY HOPE IS.
MEGYN: GENE, WHAT, WHAT
HAPPENED IN TERMS OF
CONTACTING THEIR PARENTS?
THE PARENTS OF THESE
CHILDREN WERE FRANTIC THAT
AFTERNOON.
OF COURSE I'M SURE THE
CHILDREN WANTED NOTHING MORE
TO SEE THEIR MOMS AND DADS
AS SOON AS THEY COULD.
HOW DID YOU MAKE THOSE PHONE
CALLS?
HOW DID THAT HAPPEN?
>> WELL WE STARTED CALLING
THEIR NUMBERS BECAUSE THEY
TOLD US THEIR NUMBERS BUT WE
WOULD GET THEIR HOME PHONES
THE SCHOOL BUS DRIVER HAD
THE PRESENCE OF MIND TO CALL
HER SUPERVISOR WHO MUST HAVE
HAD THEIR CONTACT LIST,
THEIR, ALL THE DETAILS OF
THEIR CONTACT.
AND SHE STARTED CALLING THE
PARENTS FROM SOME OFFICE I
ASSUME.
AND THEN THE PARENTS START
COMING.
AND WHEN THEY CAME IN I FELT
SO JOYFUL.
I FELT MORE JOYFUL THAN I
COULD EVER TELL YOU.
AND THERE WAS A HUSH IN THE
ROOM AND I THINK THE KIDS
SPOKE VERY HALTINGLY AND
QUIETLY AS IF THEY WERE
WHISPERING A HORRIBLE SECRET
BUT THEIR PARENTS WERE SO
RELIEVED AND I WAS SO HAPPY.
I WAS SO HAPPY FOR THEM.
MEGYN: MY GOODNESS I CAN'T
IMAGINE FOR THOSE PARENTS
HEARING THAT THEIR CHILDREN
WERE SAFE AND AT THIS OTHER
LOCATION BECAUSE PARENTS
WERE WAITING FOR CHILDREN AT
THE FIREHOUSE.
THAT'S WHERE POLICE HAVE
DIRECTED THEM.
THESE PARENTS CHILDREN WERE
NOT SHOWING UP AT THE
FIREHOUSE, YET THEY WERE AT
THIS RESPITE AND RESCUED
THEMSELVES AND WITH THE HELP
OF YOU AND THAT BUS DRIVER
STAYING SAFE.
GENE, I KNOW THAT SADLY
THOSE WERE NOT THE ONLY
PARENTS YOU FACED THAT DAY.
AFTER THE CHILDREN WERE,
WENT HOME WITH THEIR PARENTS
YOU GOT ANOTHER KNOCK AT THE
DOOR?
>> THIS IS THE WORST THING
THAT HAPPENED.
THIS BEAUTIFUL WOMAN CAME TO
MY DOOR.
SHE WAS SO PRETTY BUT HER
FACE WAS FROZEN.
IT WAS FROZEN IN FEAR.
IT LOOKED, LOOKED LIKE STONE
AND SHE WAS LOOKING FOR HER
SON.
I KNOW SHE FELT GOD WAS
GOING TO GIVE HER A MIRACLE
AND SO DID I.
SHE NAMED HER SON AND SHE
SAID, IS MY SON HERE?
AND I, SHE SAID I HEARD SIX
KIDS WERE HERE?
AND I SAID NO, HE'S NOT BUT
MAYBE HE IS AT THE
FIREHOUSE.
THIS WAS WELL AFTER, I THINK
THE CHILDREN HAD BEEN
ACCOUNTED FOR.
AND I WALKED DOWN TO THE
FIREHOUSE AND I LOST HER.
I SHY SHE WENT WENT AWAY.
LATER IN THE DAY I LOOKED AT
THE CASUALTY LIST AND, AND
HER SON WAS ON IT.
AND I WANT TO SEE THIS WOMAN
AND SHAKE HER HAND AND HOLD
HER.
I WANT TO PRAY FOR HER.
I, I CAN'T IMAGINE, I CAN'T
IMAGINE WHAT SHE
EXPERIENCED.
I WISH THAT BOY HAD BEEN
SITTING ON THE COUCH.
I WISH I COULD HAVE GIVEN
HER BOY BUT HE PERISHED.
MEGYN: I KNOW --
>> FOR NO REASON.
MEGYN: YOU CAN UNDERSTAND
THE DESPERATION OF THOSE
PARENTS ONCE THEY HEARD THAT
THERE WERE SOME CHILDREN WHO
HAD SAVED THEMSELVES AND
GOTTEN TO SAFETY AND WANTING
TO HOLD ONTO HOPE THAT THEIR
OWN CHILD MIGHT HAVE BEEN
ONE OF THEM.
I WANT TO END ON THIS, GENE.
I KNOW YOU SAID IN THE
INTERVIEW YOU WANT TO SEE
THESE CHILDREN AGAIN.
YOU KNOW THE PARENTS ARE
COMFORTING THEIR FRIENDS,
THE PARENTS OF THE CHILDREN
WHO FOUND THEMSELVES AT YOUR
HOUSE THAT DAY ARE THE LUCKY
ONES.
THEY'RE COMFORTING FRIEND
AND GOING TO FUNERALS THIS
WEEK.
WHY IS IT IMPORTANT FOR YOU
TO SEE THE SIX YOUNG
CHILDREN AND THEIR FOLKS
AGAIN?
>> WELL, IT IS WHAT KEEPS ME
DOING THESE INTERVIEWS.
IT IS WHAT LET'S ME SLEEP A
LITTLE AT NIGHT.
I WANT THEM TO CALL ME.
GRAND P, OR UNCLE GENE OR
THAT GUY, OR HEY YOU.
I WANT TO HOLD THEM.
I WANT TO BE WITH THEM.
I WANT TO TELL THEM THAT
THERE IS LIGHT AFTER THE
DARKNESS.
I WANT TO READ TO THEM.
I WANT TO READ A BOOK TO
THEM.
I WANT TO BE WITH THEM.
I WANT TO GIVE THEM A
SPECIAL GIFT FOR CHRISTMAS.
I WANT TO TELL THEM THAT I
WILL LOVE THEM FOREVER AND .
THEY WILL BE IN MY HEART
FOREVER AND EVER.
I PRAY THAT THEIR PARENTS
WILL CALL ME WHEN THEY CAN.
I KNOW THEY WILL.
MEGYN: YOU'VE ALREADY GIVE
10:00 THEM A SPECIAL GIFT.
YOU WERE THERE.
YOU PROVIDED SAFETY, A
STUFFED ANIMAL.
A PLACE OF WARMTH AND SAFETY
WHEN THEY HAD COME FROM
SOMETHING VERY DIFFERENT
MOMENTS EARLIER.
I KNOW THAT YOU HAVE A
BACKGROUND IN PSYCHOLOGY AND
YOU SAID YOUR DEGREE DID NOT
GET YOU THROUGH THIS.
IT WAS YOUR GRANDKIDS,
SEEING YOUR OWN GRANDKIDS
FACES IN YOUR MINDS, THAT IS
WHAT TAUGHT YOU EVERYTHING
YOU NEEDED TO KNOW.
GENE ROSEN, GOD BLESS YOU.
THANK YOU FOR BEING HERE AND
TELLING YOUR STORY, SIR.
>> THANK YOU, MEGYN.
MEGYN: WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
MEGYN: ONE INCREDIBLE GUEST
GENE ROSEN WAS AND WHAT AN
INCREDIBLE STORY AND PART OF
HIS STORY WE DIDN'T GET TO
ON CAMERA ABOUT HOW ONE OF
THE LITTLE GIRLS WHO WAS
WITH HIM IN THAT HOUSE
REALLY DIDN'T SAY MUCH THE
ENTIRE TIME BUT CLUTCHED
ONTO A STILL STUFFED
DALMATION HE GAVE HER AND
STARED OUT THE WINDOW THE
WHOLE TIME LOOKING FOR HER
PARENTS WHO CAME TO GET HER.
AFTER OUR INTERVIEW ENDED OF
MR. ROSEN.
THE GRAND PARENT OF THAT
LITTLE GIRL WENT OVER TO HIM
ON CAMERA, THAT OUR CAMERAS
SHOT THAT WE ARE NOT GOING
TO SHOW BECAUSE IT WAS A
PRIVATE MOMENT BUT THE TWO
MEN SHARED SOMETHING
SPECIAL.
WE'RE ALL GRATEFUL THAT
THOSE CHILDREN MADE IT OUT
ALIVE.
WE NEED TO LIGHTEN THE MOOD
A LITTLE BIT.
THERE IS NO BETTER WAY TO DO
THAT AS YOU KNOW ON THIS
BROADCAST IS "KELLY'S COURT".
AND WE HAVE A GOOD ONE FOR
YOU TODAY.
THE COURT IS BACK IN SESSION
AND ON THE DOCKET TODAY, A
MICHIGAN MAN FACING JAIL
TIME AFTER HE TRIED TO MAKE
A CITZENS' ARREST OF A
POLICE OFFICER.
THE MAN, APPARENTLY LOSING
IT AFTER HE SAYS HE SAW THE
COP DRIVING WITHOUT A
SEATBELT ON AND THAT IS NOT
ALL.
LISTEN.
>> YOU ARE REQUIRED BY LAW
TO WEAR YOUR SEATBELT.
PUT YOUR DAMN SEATBELT ON.
PULL IT OVER! PULL YOUR
VEHICLE OVER! YOU UNDERSTAND
RIGHT NOW! WHO THE HELL DO
YOU THINK YOU ARE.
PULL YOUR [BLEEP] OVER!.
MEGYN: THE MAN BEHIND THE
ATTEMPTED CITZENS' ARREST IS
SET TO GO TO TRIAL ON THIS
TWO MONTHS FROM NOW.
NO PLEA DEAL COULD BE
REACHED BUT HE HAS BEEN
CHARGED WITH RECKLESS
DRIVING.
JOINING ME NOW, DAVID WE'LL,
FORMER PROSECUTOR AND
DEFENSE ATTORNEY AND RYAN
CLAYPOOL THE SAME.
GENTLEMEN.
>> GOOD MORNING, MEGYN.
MEGYN: THIS MAN IS VERY
UNHAPPY.
VERY UNHAPPY.
HIS NAME IS STEVEN McCLAIN.
HE IS 60 YEARS OLD.
AND HE SAYS THE COP WAS
VIOLATING ALL SORTS OF LAWS
AND SO BRIAN, DID HE HAVE
THE RIGHT TO TRY TO MAKE A
CITZENS' ARREST?
>> MEGYN, WAIT A MINUTE.
THERE IS A NEWS FLASH.
THE VERDICT ACTUALLY CAME
IN.
THE JUDGE FOUND HIM GUILTY
AND SENTENCED HIM TO 30 DAYS
IN MY 7-YEAR-OLD LITTLE
GIRL'S ETIQUETTE AND MANNERS
CLASS.
THAT IS PROPER SENTENCE.
MEGYN: HE IS ONLY KIDDING.
THEY'RE GOING TO TRIAL WHICH
IS NUTS.
THAT IS NUTS.
HE IS CHARGED WITH RECKLESS
DRIVING.
HE SHOWS UP THE OTHER DAY
FOR COURT HEARING.
THEY'RE GOING TO TRIAL.
THEY'RE HAVING A JURY TRIAL.
THE GUY ACCUSING THE COPS.
>> SORRY ABOUT THAT.
BACK TO THE LEGAL ISSUE, NO,
HE CAN'T MAKE A CITZENS'
ARREST.
I CHECKED THE MICHIGAN
STATUTE.
THE ONLY TIME YOU CAN MAKE A
CITZENS' ARREST, MEGYN, IF
IS FELONY IS COMMITTED IN
YOUR HOUSE OR SEE A FELONY
BEING COMMITTED IN THE
PUBLIC OR A POLICE OFFICER
ASKS YOU TO ASSIST IN
APPREHENDING A SUSPECT.
NONE OF THOSE THINGS
HAPPENED HERE.
HE HAD NO RIGHT TO CARRY OUT
A CITZENS' ARREST.
MEGYN: SO WHAT, DAVID?
THE POLICE CAN DRIVE WITH
IMPUNITY AND ACCORDING TO
MR. McCLAIN THE COP WAS
SPEEDING, WASN'T WEARING HIS
SEATBELT AND WAS ENDANGERING
A K-9, A DOG WHO WAS IN THE
BACK OF HIS VEHICLE.
>> THIS MR. McCLAIN IS
LOOKING OUT FOR THE FOLKS,
MEGYN, IN THIS CASE LAW
ENFORCEMENT.
HE HAS TREMENDOUS CONCERN
FOR THEIR SAFETY.
LOOK, WAS THIS A LITTLE
OVERZEALOUS?
YES.
THANKFULLY HE DIDN'T DO A
PIT MANEUVER.
HE DIDN'T LAY DOWN SPIKE
STRESS.
HE USED HIS CAMERA.
YOU THINK THIS HAD SOMETHING
TO DO WITH A YOUTUBE MOMENT
I GUESS?
MEGYN: NO.
>> MICHIGAN THERE IS
RECKLESS DRIVING AND
CARELESS DRIVING.
WAS HE ENGAGING IN RECKLESS
DRIVING ENDANKING SAFETY OF
OTHERS AND HIMSELF?
I DON'T THINK SO.
WAS IT CARELESS?
POSSIBLY.
MEGYN: I DON'T THINK HE WAS
LOOKING FOR A YOUTUBE
MOMENT.
THE REPORTS SAY THIS GUY
DRIVES AROUND TAKING
PICTURES OF COPS NOT WEARING
SEATBELTS.
HE HAS 30 OR 60 OTHER
INSTANCES DOING THIS.
I CAN'T REMEMBER NUMBER.
THIS IS REAL ISSUE FOR HIM.
LISTEN HOW ANGRY HE IS IS.
PLAY SOUND BITE NUMBER ONE.
>> OKAY.
>> WHEN THE LIGHT TURNED
GREEN HE TOOK OFF AT SUCH A
HIGH RATE OF SPEED AND I
COULD SEE IT WAS A K-9 UNIT.
I WAS CONCERNED FOR THE
POSSIBILITY OF A DOG BEING
INSIDE.
I SAID, SIR, YOU NEED TO
WEAR YOUR SEATBELT.
HE STARTED LAUGHING.
THAT SET ME OFF.
I WAS MAD AS HELL.
MEGYN: SO I MEAN, BRIAN,
DOES IT AMOUNT TO RECKLESS
DRIVING FOR HIM TO DO IT?
>> MEGYN HE WAS LOOKING OUT
THE WINDOW TALKING TO A
POLICE OFFICER.
MEGYN: SO WAS THE POLICE
OFFICER.
>> POLICE OFFICER IS
REACTING TO HIM.
HE INITIATED.
HE CAN'T DRIVE A CAR LOOKING
OUT YOUR WINDOW.
MEGYN: HE WAS REACTING TO A
POLICE OFFICER GOING TOO
FAST AND NOT LOOKING OUT FOR
THE DOG TO OUT IN THE BACK.
>> I WILL SEND McCLAIN A
E-MAIL.
MAKE A LIST OF COMMUNITY
SERVICE ORGANIZATIONS HE
COULD VOLUNTEER TO HELP WITH
BECAUSE HE HAS WAY TOO MANY
TIME ON HIS HANDS.
MEGYN: THE RULES APPLY TO
ALL OF US, DO THEY NOT,
DAVID?
AS I RAID THE RULES, POLICE
GET EXCEPTIONS FOR TRAFFIC
RULES WHEN THEY'RE IN
PURSUIT AND THEY HAVE SIRENS
ON.
THIS WASN'T THAT SITUATION.
HOW DO WE HOLD THEM
ACCOUNTABLE?
>> HE WASN'T SPEEDING.
THERE WERE NO SIRENS ON.
SAME LAWS THAT APPLY TO YOU,
ME, AND BRIAN APPLY TO HIM.
HE WAS NOT WEARING SEAT
BELT.
HE WAS NOT TRYING TO EFFECT
A CITZENS' ARREST.
HE WAS TRYING TO STOP THE
OFFICER.
IF THE OFFICER WAS NOT
COMPLIANT WITH THE LAW.
I WAS GOING TO CALL THE
POLICE DEPARTMENT AND COME
OVER AND EFFECT A CITATION.
MEGYN: TRYING TO GET A COP
ARRESTED.
90 DAYS IN JAIL WOULD BE A
WHOPPER FOR THIS GUY.
WE'LL SEE HOW THE TRIAL
GOES.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
I'VE GOTINE GRAMS OF PROTEIN.
THAT'S THREE TIMES MORE THAN ME!
[ Female Announcer ]
Ensure Clear.
NINE GRAMS PROTEIN. ZERO FAT.
IN BLUEBERRY/POMEGRANATE
AND PEACH.
I just finished a bowl of your
new Light Chicken Pot Pie Soup
and it's so rich
and creamy...
is it really 100 calories?
Let me put you on webcan...
...lean roasted chicken...
and a creamy broth
Mmm
I can still see you.
[ Male announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
♪ .
MEGYN: FOR YEARS ONE
NEW JERSEY TOWN HAS BEEN
MYSTERIOUSLY LOSING PINE
TREES AROUND CHRISTMASTIME.
TOWN LEADERS SAY IT'S
RESIDENTS TRYING TO STEAL A
FREE CHRISTMAS TREE.
SO HOW EXACTLY SHOULD THEY
CRACK DOWN ON THAT?
WELL APPARENTLY THE SOLUTION
HAS BEEN RIGHT UNDER THEIR
NOSE THE WHOLE TIME.
NOTHING SAYS CHRISTMAS LIKE
STEALING, TRACE.
>> Reporter: NOTHING DOES.
THIS PORT REPUBLIC,
NEW JERSEY, HAS A QUAINT
LITTLE AREA WITH TENNIS
COURTS AND ICE SKATING RING
BUT IT GETS WINDY.
THEY PUT UP THE PINE TREES
TO ACT AS WIND BARRIER.
WOULDN'T YOU KNOW, EVERY
CHRISTMAS SOMEBODY COMES BUY
TO STEAL A FEW OF CHRISTMAS
TREES, THE MAYOR, THAT MAN
RIGHT THERE, WENT TO HIS
FRIENDS IN THE FOREST
SERVICE TO COME UP WITH A
STINKY REPELLANT.
THEY MIXED TWO CONTAINERS OF
DEER REPELLANT WITH MOSS
BUNKER JUICE.
LISTEN.
>> MOSS BUNKER JUICE THEY
ACTUALLY USE IN FERTILIZER.
HE SAID MIX THAT WITH THIS
THING.
DO IT TWICE.
PUT TWO COATS ON IT.
AND WHEN YOU GET WITHIN FIVE
FOOT OF THAT TREE YOU'RE NOT
GOING TO WANT TO TAKE IT
INTO YOUR LIVING ROOM.
>> Reporter: OH, NO.
WHAT DOES IT SMELL LIKE?
SULFUR WITH A HINT OF ROTTEN
EGGS, WITH ANOTHER HINT OF
ROTTEN FISH.
SINCE THEY SPRAYED THE
REPELLANT ALL OVER THE TREES,
NOT A SINGLE ONE, MEGYN HAS
BEEN STOLEN.
NOT A SINGLE ONE.
KIND OF BUMMED THE MAYOR
OUT.
BECAUSE HE WANTED TO DRIVE
AROUND NEIGHBORHOODS TO SEE
IF ANYBODY TOSSED OUT THE
TREE BECAUSE IT SMELLED SO
BADLY.
ONCE YOU GET IN THE HOUSE
AND HEATS UP THE SMELL GETS
FOUR TIMES WORSE THAN
LEAVING IT OUT IN THE COLD.
MEGYN: CLEVER SOLUTION
ACTUALLY.
>> Reporter: IS.
MEGYN: GOOD TO KNOW.
THANKS, TRACE.
>> Reporter: OKAY.
MEGYN: WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
DON'T GO AWAY.
I GAVE BIRTH TO MY DAUGHTER
ON MAY 18TH,
FIVE DAYS LATER,
I HAD A MASSIVE HEART ATTACK.
BAYER ASPIRIN WAS THE FIRST
THING THE EMTS GAVE ME.
NOW, I'M ON
A BAYER ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Male Announcer ] BE SURE
TO TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE YOU BEGIN
AN ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Woman ]
LEARN FROM MY STORY.
>>Megyn: A PHOTO SHARING
SERVICE HAS CHANGED THEIR