THAT KNOCK DOWN DRAGOUT FIGHT
STARTED AS COMEDY BUT QUICKLY IT
TURNED VERY VERY REAL.
MASCOTS GETTING VIOLENT.
THE RAM AND THE PANTHER PULLING
EACH OTHER TO THE GROUND AND
THROWING PUNCHES.
THE HALFTIME BRAWL DIDN'T END
UNTIL OTHERS STEPPED IN TO PULL
THE MASCOTS APART, BUT DON'T
WORRY.
THE RAM AND THE PANTHER WERE NOT
HURT.
THAT'S THE LAST CALL.
THANKS FOR BEING WITH US
TONIGHT.
SEE YOU TOMORROW NIGHT.
GO TO GRETAWIRE.COM.
THERE'S AN OPEN THREAD.
TELL US WHAT YOU THOUGHT ABOUT
TONIGHT'S SHOW.
GRETAWEAR.COM.
GOODNIGHT FROM WASHINGTON.
>> Eric: THIS IS A FOX NEWS
ALERT.
WE HAVE BREAKING NEWS ON TWO
BIG STORIES AT THIS HOUR.
YOU ARE LOOKING LIVE AT THE
WHITE HOUSE WHERE PRESIDENT
OBAMA AND HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER ARE ABOUT TO MEET TO
DISCUSS THE LOOMING FISCAL
CLIFF.
THIS IS A SURPRISE MEETING,
ONE THAT WE LEARNED ABOUT A
SHORT TIME AGO.
BOEHNER IS MAKING HIS WAY OVER
THERE RIGHT NOW.
THE OTHER BREAKING NEWS IS
THAT U.N. AMBASSADOR SUSAN
RICE JUST REMOVED HER NAME
FROM CONSIDERATION FOR THE
COVETED SECRETARY OF STATE
JOB, FOLLOWING THE THEORY OVER
HER RESPONSE TO THE ATTACK ON
THE CONSULATE IN BENGHAZI.
ED HENRY HAS MORE ON BOTH
BREAKING STORIES.
TAKE IT AWAY.
>> Reporter: YOU ARE RIGHT.
SPEAKER BOEHNER LEFT THE
CAPITAL AND EXPECTED TO ARRIVE
AT THE WHITE HOUSE IN A
MOMENT.
THIS COULD NOT PUT MORE
EXPLANATION POINT HOW CRITICAL
THIS MEETING IS.
WE ARE RUNNING UP AGAINST THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
WE HEARD FROM FIRMS THAT
UNLESS A FRAMEWORK FOR A DEAL
IS FORGED IN THE NEXT FEW DAYS
THEY ARE GOING TO RUN OUT OF
TIME IN ORDER ACTUALLY MOVE
WHATEVER DEAL THEY COME UP
WITH THROUGH BOTH CHANGES TO
THE HOUSE AND THE SENATE.
THIS IS WHY I GOT NEW
INFORMATION THAT LAST NIGHT
SENATE MAJORITY LEADER HARRY
REID MET IN A PRIVATE DINNER
AND HE WAS SAYING HE BELIEVES
IT'S NEARLY IMPOSSIBLE TO GET
THE FISCAL CLIFF DEAL DONE
BEFORE CHRISTMAS.
WHAT THEY ARE FOCUSED ON IS A
SO-CALLED PLAN "B" WHERE THE
HOUSE IN THE NEXT FEW DAYS MAY
PASS EXTENSION OF THE MIDDLE
CLASS TAX CUTS.
THE OLD BUSH TAX CUTS.
THEN LET THE TAX RATES FOR THE
RICH GO UP AND FIGHT IT OUT IN
JANUARY AND FEBRUARY OVER
SPENDING CUTS.
WE'LL SEE WHETHER OR NOT
CONSERVATIVE GOES ALONG WITH
THAT, IF SPEAKER BOEHNER WAS
PARTY TO THAT.
THE SECOND BIG STORY IS SUSAN
RICE.
IN THE LAST COUPLE OF HOURS
CALLING THE PRESIDENT AND
SAYING SHE IS PULLING HER NAME
OUT OF CONSIDERATION FOR
SECRETARY OF STATE, ALL
BECAUSE OF THE CONTROVERSY
OVER BENGHAZI, HER REACTION TO
THE TERROR ATTACK, WHETHER OR
NOT SHE MISLED THE PUBLIC.
BOTTOM LINE THIS PUTS JOHN
KERRY, DEMOCRATIC SOURCES SAY,
AS THE LIKELY CONTENDER TO BE
SECRETARY OF STATE I'M SEEING
THE SUVs PULL UP WITH
SPEAKER BOEHNER RIGHT NOW.
BOTH THE STORIES BREAKING
RIGHT AS WE SPEAK.
YOU WILL SEE SPEAKER BOEHNER
IN A MOMENT.
BUT BOTTOM LINE IS YOU WILL
REMEMBER AT THE POST ELECTION
NEWS CONFERENCE, THE PRESIDENT
MADE A BIG DEAL ABOUT STANDING
UP FOR SUSAN RICE.
SAYING THAT BASICALLY, SHE
WAS --
[ INAUDIBLE ]
NOT GOING TO STAND FOR ATTACKS
THREATENED FILIBUSTER.
THIS IS A CAVE-IN BY THE
PRESIDENT.
HE GAVE IN TO THE CRITICS ON
THE HILL.
SUSAN RICE MAY NOT BE
DISAPPEARING.
IT POSTED A STORY SAYING THE
TOP DEMOCRATS SAY SHE MAY BE
THE NEXT NATIONAL SECURITY
ADVISOR HERE INSIDE THE WHITE
HOUSE.
SIGNIFICANT THAT THE PRESIDENT
APPOINTS HER TO THAT, DOESN'T
NEED SENATE CONFIRMATION, SO
REPUBLICANS CAN'T PHIL BUSTER.
THE FINAL POINT I'LL MAKE IS
DEMOCRATS ARE TELLING US THAT
CHUCK HAGEL THE FORMER
REPUBLICAN SENATOR IS NOW THE
LEADING CONTENDER TO BE THE
NEXT DEFENSE SECRETARY.
THE RICE MOVE POSSIBLE KERRY
ELEVATION TO SECRETARY OF
STATE IS PART OF A BROADER
LOOK AT REFURBISHMENT.
EXPECTING A NEW NATIONAL
SECURITY TEAM FOR PRESIDENT TO
ANNOUNCE AS EARLY AS NEXT
WEEK.
>> Eric: THANK YOU, ED
HENRY.
IF YOU HEAR ANYTHING ELSE, GET
BACK TO US AND WE'LL GO BACK
TO YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Eric: YOU HEAR THIS, AND
I HEARD YOU HUMMING, WHICH
PART?
WHAT WAS CONCERNING TO YOU?
>> Dana: THE PIECE ABOUT THE
FISCAL CLIFF FIRST.
YOU THINK THEY HAVE HAD A YEAR
TO WORK ON THAT THE DEMOCRATS
AND REPUBLICANS COULD COME
TOGETHER.
I THINK WHAT HARRY REID HEARD
LAST NIGHT FROM THE DEMOCRATS
IS WE ARE NOT GOING TO DO
ANYTHING.
THIS IS REPORTED IN THE
NATIONAL JOURNAL TODAY.
NOT GOING TO DO ANYTHING TO
MAKE ANY CHANGE OR SACRIFICE
BENEFIT FOR SOCIAL SECURITY,
MEDICARE OR MEDICAID.
THAT WOULD BE A CONDITION OF
SPEAKER BOEHNER, WHICH IS IF
WE GIVE YOU THE REVENUE YOU
HAVE TO HELP US ON THE
SPENDING SIDE, ON THE
ENTITLEMENT ISSUE.
REID SAID I CAN'T GET
DEMOCRATS TO SUPPORT THAT.
SO NOW BOEHNER IS GOING UP TO
SAY ALL RIGHT, WHERE ARE WE?
MAYBE THEY'LL GET TO
SOMETHING.
IF THEY PUSH THIS ON THE NEXT
YEAR, I THINK IT'S A GOOD
THING BECAUSE, IN SOME WAYS,
BECAUSE YOU A NEW CONGRESS AND
NEW MEMBERS.
MAYBE BECAUSE THEY ARE GOING
OUT TO LIVE UNDER THE DECISION
THAT WOULD BE MADE THIS MONTH,
MAYBE IT'S OKAY TO HAVE THEM
BE ABLE TO WEIGH IN ON IT.
>> Eric: HANG ON TO THE
AMBASSADOR RICE COMMENT COMMENTA
MINUTE.
BOB, YOU WERE FIST-PUMPING
WHILE HEARING HENRY SAY THERE
IS A MEETING AND THEY MAY KICK
PART OF IT DOWN THE ROAD.
>> Eric: WHAT IS HAPPENING
HERE -- NORTH DAKOTA IS
GETTING TO POINT YOU CAN'T
WRITE LEGISLATION, NOT ENOUGH
TIME TO WRITE LEGISLATION
REVAMPING SOCIAL SECURITY AND
MEDICARE.
THEY CAN PASS THE TAX CUTS.
LEAVE THE TOP 2%, $250,000
THEIR TAXES WILL GO UP.
THEY HAVE TO HAVE LANGUAGE
THERE TO DEAL WITH THE
REPUBLICAN CONCERN ABOUT
ENTITLEMENT.
I THINK IT WILL BE ALONG THE
LINES OF SEQUESTRATION.
IF YOU DON'T HAVE AN AGREEMENT
ON SOCIAL SECURITY, MEDICARE
OR MEDICAID, SOCIAL SECURITY
OR MEDICARE AT A CERTAIN
POINT, DATE CERTAIN THERE WILL
BE AUTOMATIC CUTS IN PROGRAMS.
>> Andrea: THEY WILL TAKE
AWAY THE DEFENSE CUTS AND
PUSH --
>> Dana: THEY WILL PUSH OFF
THE DEFENSE CUTS.
PUSH THEM OFF.
>> Andrea: HOW HOWARDLY IS
THAT?
I THINK A LOT OF MEMBERS
SECRETLY WANTED THE CUTS TO
TAKE PLACE SO THEY DON'T TAKE
A STAND AND THEY DON'T HAVE TO
VOTE EITHER FOR HIGHER TAXES
OR ON ENTITLEMENTS.
TODAY IS -- BOB IS RIGHT.
TODAY IS THE LAST DAY THAT
THEY NEED TO COME UP WITH A
DEAL BECAUSE THERE IS A TIME
CRUNCH ON THE LEGISLATION.
GETTING IT THROUGH.
BUT I THINK IT'S DISINGENUOUS
FOR JAY CARNEY TO COME OUT AND
SAY TODAY, REPUBLICANS HAVEN'T
MOVED AT ALL.
REPUBLICANS HAVE MOVED.
THEY HAVE COME TO THE TABLE
WITH REVENUE RAISERS.
IT'S THE DEMOCRATS THAT
HAVEN'T MOVED AT ALL.
I DO THINK THAT AFTER THE
FIRST OF THE YEAR, IT'S NOT
GOOD TO HAVE THE FIGHT.
THE REASON FOR THAT IS THEY
ARE JUST FIGHTING OVER THE TAX
CUTS FOR THE RICH, THAT IS A
P.R. BATTLE THAT THE PRESIDENT
WANTS, BECAUSE HE KNOWS HE
WILL WIN.
>> Greg: THIS WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE ABOUT SPENDING, AND
TAXES.
NOW IT'S JUST ABOUT TAXES.
IT'S LIKE IGNORING CANCER AND
TREATING A COLD SORE.
IT'S ALWAYS GOING TO BE ABOUT
SPENDING.
THE WORST THING, PRESIDENT
OBAMA NEVER HAS TO EXPLAIN,
EVER, WHY RAISING TAXES ON THE
2% WOULD HELP.
OR HURT THE ECONOMY.
MOST PEOPLE BELIEVE THAT IT
WILL HURT THE ECONOMY.
HE GETS MORE FREE RIDES THAN A
HOT HITCHHIKER.
AT SOME POINT, WE HAVE TO
QUESTION PRESIDENT OBAMA'S
OBSESSION WITH A CERTAIN
SEGMENT OF THE POPULATION.
IF THE RICH WERE JUSTIN
BIEBER, OBAMA WOULD BE
ARRESTED FOR STALKING.
>> Eric: THAT IS ANOTHER
GREAT LINE.
>> Bob: ONE THING HE HAS
GOING FOR HIM IS THE POLLS
THAT ARE OUT, TWO THINGS IN
THE POLLS THAT JUST CAME OUT
FROM PEW AND ABC, "WASHINGTON
POST," PEOPLE DO WANT SPENDING
CUTS.
THEY THINK IT'S VERY
IMPORTANT.
BUT THEY OVERWHELMINGLY FAVOR
INCREASE IN TAXES.
>> IF YOU DON'T OFFER THE
ALTERNATIVE, YOU KNOW, CLOSING
THE LOOPHOLES AND FINDING, YOU
KNOW, GETTING RID OF THE
BRACKETS, NOBODY EVER PUTS
THAT IN A POLL.
WHEN THEY DO PUT IN A POLL
THAT PEOPLE SHY AWAY FROM
INCREASING TAXES.
>> Eric: WE HAVE A COUPLE OF
POLLS.
PULL UP THE FIRST ONE.
HOW THE BUDGET CONTROL, HOW
THE BUDGET SHOULD BE FIXED.
49% SAY LAWMAKERS WILL REACH
AN AGREEMENT.
34% SAID PUSH THEM OVER THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT WILL HAPPEN
IN THIS HOUR, IN THIS MEETING
SO WE COULD STILL GO OVER THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
THE SECOND POLL, THE BEST WAY
OR FIX THIS BUDGET PROBLEM,
57%.
MOSTLY SPENDING CUTS.
RAISE MY TAXES.
>> Dana: THIS IS THE PROBLEM
THAT THE DEMOCRATS ARE
STARTING TO REALIZE, THEY LET
THIS GO ON TOO LONG.
YOU NEVER UNDER ESTIMATE THE
OBAMA ADMINISTRATION TENDENCY
TO OVERPLAY THEIR HAND.
YES, THEY HAD A GOOD HAND, BUT
THEY DO TOO MUCH.
THEN THE PUBLIC CATCHES UP
WITH WHAT IS GOING ON HERE.
THEY SAY WAIT A SECOND, FOR
SPENDING CUTS AND THE NEW
STORIES ARE STARTING TO
CHANGE.
THAT THE DEMOCRATS SAY THEY
ARE NOT FOR THAT.
>> Bob: THE PEOPLE BLAME
REPUBLICANS IF IT DOESN'T
WORK.
THEY BLAME OBAMA.
IF YOU BROUGHT UP A NUMBER
SHOULD RICH PEOPLE GET TAX
INCREASES OVERWHELMINGLY THEY
YES.
>> Eric: LET'S TALK ABOUT
WHAT IS GOING ON.
PRESIDENT OBAMA CAME OUT AND
SAID I WANT 1.6 TRILLION IN
NEW REVENUES.
JOHN BOEHNER SAYS WE WILL GIVE
YOU $800 EXAMPLE IN NEW
REVENUE.
OBAMA CAME DOWN TO
$1.4 TRILLION.
BOEHNER HASN'T COME BACK YET.
IF BOEHNER OFFERS $1 TRILLION
NEW REVENUES CAN IT PASS THE
HOUSE?
>> Andrea: GREAT QUESTION.
WE ARE SITTING AROUND THE
TABLE SITTING ABOUT DEAL THAT
BOEHNER BROKERS.
HE HAS TO GO BACK TO THE
MEMBERS TO GET THE DEAL
THROUGH THE HOUSE.
I'M NOT SO SURE ABOUT IT.
I KNOW WHAT HE WON'T GET
THROUGH THE HOUSE, RAISING
TAXES.
HE IS NOT GOING TO GET SOME
TAX RAISING COMPROMISE
TOGETHER.
THERE IS NO HOUSE MEMBER WHEN
THEY KNOW THEY HAVE TO RUN FOR
RE-ELECTION EVERY TWO YEARS,
THAT IS GOING TO VOTE FOR A
TAX INCREASE.
HOW WOULD THEY GET THROUGH A
PRIMARY?
>> Bob: THEY WILL VOTE ON
CUTTING TAXES ON EVERYBODY BUT
THE 2%.
THAT IS POLITICALLY SELLABLE.
>> Dana: NO.
EXTENDING THE BUSH TAX CUTS
FOR EVERYBODY.
IT'S NOT OBAMA'S TAX CUTS.
>> Bob: YOU EXTEND IT FOR
EVERYBODY EXCEPT FOR THAT
GROUP OF PEOPLE.
>> Eric: IF THEY ARE NOT --
LET ME ASK YOU.
>> Dana: I SEE.
>> Eric: WILL THEY GET --
>> Dana: I SEE WHAT HE IS
SAYING.
IT'S LIKE WHEN YOU REDUCE THE
RATE OF GROWTH, YOU GET CREDIT
FOR SAYING THAT YOU CUT
SPENDING.
IT'S A GAME.
IT'S A WORD GAME.
>> Bob: KEEP IN MIND,
WHATEVER LEGISLATION HAPPENS
CAN BE RETROACTIVELY MADE TO
JANUARY 1.
WHEN YOU GET TO JUNE WORKING
ON THIS, YOU STILL HAVE THE
DEBT CEILING ISSUE HERE.
SHE IS RIGHT TOUGH TO GET
THROUGH THE HOUSE.
BOEHNER FOR THE FIRST TIME,
UNLIKE LAST TIME, HE HAS THE
LIEUTENANTS WITH HIM.
CANADA WITH HIM, TWO OR THREE
OTHERS IN LEADERSHIP WITH HIM
ON THIS.
SO IF HE HAS THAT, HE CAN PUT
TOGETHER MAJORITY.
>> Eric: CAN YOU IMAGINE
WHAT IS GOING ON BEHIND THE
DOOR NOW?
JOHN BOEHNER HAS TO FIGURE OUT
HOW HE IS GOING TO OFFER
INCREASE REVENUE, PROBABLY
OFFER TAX INCREASES AND FIGURE
OUT HOW TO SELL IT TO THE
GROUP.
>> Greg: I GO BACK TO THE
MAXIM ABOUT OBESE PEOPLE.
THEY ARE NOT FAT BECAUSE THEY
DON'T HAVE ENOUGH FAT.
THEY'RE FAT BECAUSE THEY EAT
TOO MUCH.
THAT'S THE GOVERNMENT.
THE PROBLEM ISN'T THEY NEED
MORE MONEY.
THEY CAN'T STOP SPENDING.
EVERY TIME YOU RAISE TAXES
IT'S INJECTING A FAT PERSON
WITH TWINKIES.
>> Eric: WE HAVE TO GO.
WHAT IS THE SIGNIFICANCE OF
BOEHNER WAS SUPPOSED TO LEAVE
EITHER TONIGHT OR TOMORROW
MORNING TO GO BACK TO OHIO.
AND THIS MEETING HAPPENS.
>> Dana: THEY ALL WANT A
WEEKEND.
THE MEMBERS WANT TO GO BACK
HOME AND TOUCH BASE WITH THE
CONSTITUENTS SO OBAMA AND
BOEHNER WHO ARE ACTING LIKE
THE ADULTS HERE DECIDED TO
HAVE A MEETING.
AND TEMPORARY MEASURES ARE
VERY BAD FOR THE ECONOMY.
SO SETTING ASIDE WHAT IS GOOD
FOR REPUBLICANS OR DEMOCRATS
IF THEY KICK THIS TO JANUARY
OR FEBRUARY AND WE TALK ABOUT
IT THEN, MAYBE IT HELPS THE
MARKETS GET THROUGH THE FISCAL
CLIFF AREA.
BUT STILL A TETCH RARE MEASURE
THAT DOESN'T INVOLVE --
>> Greg: CAN WE CALL IT
SOMETHING ELSE?
FISCAL CLIFF?
CAN'T WE CALL IT SOMETHING
ELSE?
>> Dana: SURE.
>> Eric: MONETARY --
>> Greg: LIBERAL FANTASY.
>> Bob: ONE MORE THING ON
THE TABLE.
CAN OBAMA SELL CUTS IN
ENTITLEMENTS TO HIS SENATE?
>> Dana: NOT ACARDING TO
HARRY REID.
>> Eric: LEAVE IT THERE.
WE'LL STAY ON IT.
DON'T GO AWAY.
MORE ON DEVELOPING NEWS
WASHINGTON, INCLUDING
AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE.
WE'LL GET ON THAT WHEN WE COME
BACK.
♪
>> Greg: GOT TO LOVE THE
WHO.
>> Dana: WHO?
>> Greg: WHO?
GET BACK TO SUSAN RICE IN A
MINUTE BUT THEY HAVE THE LIE
OF THE YEAR, COVERUP BENGHAZI
TO WIN AN ELECTION BY OBAMA.
NO, KIDDING.
THE LEFT WING HACKS CLAIM THE
BIGGEST LIE WAS MILT'S CLAIM
THAT -- MITT'S CLAIM THAT JEEP
WAS MOVING ITS PRODUCTION TO
CHINA CAUSING A FLOOD OF
NEGATIVE PRESS DIRECTED AT
MITT.
OF COURSE IT DID.
ONLY THE AMERICAN MEDIA COULD
SEE THIS LITTLE FLUBB AS WORSE
THAN THE BUNGLED AFTERMATH
FOLLOWING THE DEATH OF FOUR
AMERICANS IN BENGHAZI.
FORGET THE OTHER LIBERAL LIES
THAT PAUL RYAN PUSHES GRANNIES
OFF THE CLIFF, REMEMBER THAT?
OR MITT MURDERED A GUY'S WIFE.
THAT WAS FUN.
MEDIA IS A SAD MIDDLE AGE MAN
AT STRIP CLUB OVERCOME BY
OBAMA LUST DIMINISHED BY
STUPIDITY.
THE EMPEROR HAS NO CLOSE
CLOTHES.
ALL THEY CAN DO IS KEEP
WHISTLING.
WHY EVERY NEWS OUTLET RAN WITH
THE FAKE AWARD.
THE BLOG CLAIMS THE PUBLIC
EXPRESSED COLLECTIVE OUTRAGE
AND THEY MUST MEAN MALE
BLOGGERS WITH PONYTAILS.
SAYING THIS IS THE REAL LIE
BUT IT'S WORSE THAN A LIE.
ABETTING THE OBAMA COVERUP,
THE MEDIA IS AN ACCESSORY
AFTER THE FACT.
WE STILL DON'T KNOW WHERE THIS
VIDEO IDEA CAME FROM, I WILL
NEVER STOP.
DON'T YOU THINK THAT IS WORSE
THAN A CRACK ABOUT JEEPS
SHIPPED TO CHINA?
THE POLITIFACT LIE OF YEAR
AWARD SHOULD GO TO POLITIFACT.
CONGRATS.
COVERING UP "O"'S MISTAKE IS
YOU CONSIDERED JOURNALISM?
A FEW MORE DEAD AN YOU'D GET
THE LIAR'S ACHIEVEMENT AWARD.
SUSAN RICE REMOVED HER NAME.
I DIDN'T KNOW YOU COULD DO
THAT.
I COULD THEORETICALLY REMOVE
MY NAME FROM THE STRAWBERRY
CAKE AMBASSADORSHIP.
>> Dana: EVERY DAY I COULD
MAKE AN ANNOUNCEMENT I AM
GOING TO WITHDRAW MY NAME FOR
THE HELLO KITTY AMBASSADORSHIP
AT TIMES SQUARE.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU SEE THEM.
THEY TRY TO RECRUIT ME.
>> Andrea: MISS UNIVERSE.
>> Dana: I UNDERSTAND THEY
WANT THE NEWS FIGHT AND WHY
THEY GO AGAINST THE
REPUBLICANS, THE MEAN GUYS.
HERE IS THE THING.
IT WASN'T JUST ABOUT BENGHAZI
SHE WAS NOT LOOKED AT TO BE
THE NEXT BEST SECRETARY OF
STATE.
IT'S A MODERATE SENATOR.
SENATOR COLLINS SAYING I'M NOT
FOR THIS.
SEVERAL REASONS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA LOST HIS FIRST
POLITICAL GAMBLE OF A SECOND
TERM.
THEN THEY ARE MAGNIFYING IT,
MAKING A BIG ANNOUNCEMENT.
SHE IS DOING EXCLUSIVE
INTERVIEW TONIGHT WITH NBC.
SHE WAS NEVER OFFICIALLY
NOMINATED FOR ANYTHING.
YOU CAN'T WITHDRAWAL YOUR NAME
FROM CONSIDERATION.
WE COULD DO THAT ALL DAY LONG.
GET MAYBE GOOD PRESS.
>> Eric: HE NEVER IN ANY --
>> Bob: HE NEVER IN ANY WAY,
SHAPE OR FORM HINTED SHE WOULD
BE THE SECRETARY OF STATE
NOMINEE.
>> Dana: YES, HE --
>> Bob: NO, HE DEFENDED HER.
BUT I NEVER HEARD HIM SAY
ANYTHING ABOUT SECRETARY OF
STATE.
>> Andrea: DO YOU WANT TO
USE THIS OPPORTUNITY MAYBE TO
WITHDRAWAL CONSIDERATION OF
YOUR CANDIDACY FOR SEXIEST MAN
ALIVE
>> Bob: I CAN'T DO THAT.
NOBODY ELSE COULD TAKE MY
PLACE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Eric: THE TIMING OF THIS,
AMBASSADOR RICE, MAYBE AS YOU
POINT OUT SUSAN COLLINS, JOHN HD
SAID I'M GOING TO GIVE HER A
BREAK.
SEE WHAT SHE HAS TO SAY.
McCAIN, LINDSEY GRAHAM AND
COLIN, COUPLE -- AND AYOTTE
SPENT HOURS WITH HER BEHIND
CLOSED DOORS AND CAME OUT WITH
A FACE LIKE UH-OH, THIS IS
GOING TO BE A PROBLEM.
THEY WERE TRYING TO GIVE HER
THE BENEFIT OF THE DOUBT AND
REALIZED THEY COULDN'T SHE HAS
NO CHOICE.
>> Dana: THERE IS AN ART OF
FLOATING SOMEBODY'S FAME FOR
SOMETHING, THEY DIDN'T DO IT
WELL.
>> Andrea: THEY CREATED THIS
MESS FROM DAY ONE.
THEY FLOATED HER NAME.
THEY ARE THE ONES THAT PUSHED
IT.
NOW, THEY THINK THIS IS GOOD
FOR THEM.
IT REALLY DO THINK THIS IS
GOOD FOR THEM.
THE PRESIDENT ISSUED A
STATEMENT THAT SAID WE CAN'T
BELIEVE, WE'RE DISAPPOINTED IN
REPUBLICANS.
IF I WERE HER, I WOULD SAY YOU
KNOW WHAT?
SPARE ME.
YOU HAVE HAVE DONE ENOUGH TO
HURT ME.
NOW I LOOK LIKE A VICTIM.
SHE SHOULD HAVE SAID WEEKS AGO
I THINK WE TALKED ABOUT THIS
ON AMERICA'S NEWSROOM, SHE
SHOULD SAY I DON'T WANT IT.
>> Dana: HAPPY WHERE I AM.
>> Bob: IF YOU FLOAT A NAME
FOR SECRETARY OF STATE AND
DON'T DO IT BY GIVING HER
TALKING POINTS ON
CONTROVERSIAL ISSUE AND PUT IT
ON A TALK SHOW.
>> Dana: THAT AREN'T TRUE.
>> Greg: SO YOU ARE BLAMING
THE VIDEO OF HER ON SUNDAY
TALK SHOW.
THAT CREATED ANGRY MOB IN THE
WHITE HOUSE.
>> Andrea: WHO MADE THE
VIDEO?
CAN WE PUT THEM IN JAIL?
>> Greg: DO YOU KNOW WHAT IT
IS?
ONCE THEY FOUND OUT SHE WAS
WORTH $40 MILLION.
COULD IT HAVE BEEN ATTACK ON
THE SUPER RICH?
>> Eric: 1%.
>> Dana: BUT NOW THEY HAVE
JOHN KERRY.
HE IS WORTH $40 BILLION.
>> Eric: POINT SOMETHING OUT
ABOUT THE POLITIFACT THING ON
THE MONOLOGUE.
THEY'RE WRONG ON THIS.
ROMNEY IS RIGHT.
CHRYSLER IS BUILDING,
MOVING -- NOT MOVING IS
OPENING PLANTS IN CHINA,
BUILDING --
>> Dana: THAT IS NOT --
>> Bob: THAT IS NOT WHAT
ROMNEY SAID.
>> Eric: HE MISSPOKE AND
SAID JOBS.
THEY STILL HAVE OUR MONEY,
BOB.
THEY HAVE OUR MONEY OPENING
THE PLANTS.
>> Bob: ROMNEY --
>> Eric: HE WAS RIGHT.
>> Bob: HE DID IT IN OHIO.
THIS IS A BIGGER DEAL THAN
GREG MADE IT OUT TO BE.
IN OHIO, IN THE LAST PUSH FOR
THE MOST IMPORTANT STATE.
HE MADE A STATEMENT THAT
CHRYSLER WAS TAKING THE JEEPS
AND GOING TO CHINA WITH THEM.
THAT'S JUST WRONG.
FLAT-OUT WRONG.
>> Andrea: BY THE TIME THE
AD CAME OUT IT WAS FACTUALLY
CORRECT.
>> Greg: BY THE WAY, IF IT
WAS A FLUBB, WHICH -- LOOK,
HOW COULD IT BE ANY WORSE THAN
ACCUSING MITT ROMNEY OF
MURDER?
>> Dana: THEY ACTUALLY HAD
TO ADMIT THEY GOT IT WRONG.
EVEN THE PEOPLE ON THE LEFT
SAID --
>> Bob: CAN WE GO BACK TO
SUSAN RICE FOR A SECOND.
THEY TALK ABOUT HER BEING THE
NATIONAL SECURITY ADVISOR,
WHICH DOES REQUIRE SENATOR
APPROVAL.
MY TREND TOM DONAL THE CURRENT
NATIONAL SECURITY ADVISOR,
NOBODY EASILY PUSHED AROUND, I
THINK YOU LOOK AT HIM AS
POTENTIAL SECRETARY OF STATE
NOMINEE AS WELL.
>> Eric: WHAT ABOUT JOHN
KERRY?
>> Dana: HOLY FREDDIE MAC,
BATMAN.
>> Andrea: WHO IS FACT
CHECKING THE FACT CHECKERS?
HOW CAN SOMEONE CALL
THEMSELVESES A FACT CHECKER?
SO GREG, I'M JUST GOING TO
CALL MYSELF A FACT CHECKER
RIGHT NOW AND SAY THE LIE OF
THE YEAR WAS POLITIFACT BUT IT
WAS THAT ROMNEY WAS WRONG TO
CLAIM SPENDING UNDER OBAMA
ACCELERATED AT A PACE WITHOUT
PRECEDENCE IN HISTORY.
THEY SAID THAT WAS A LIE.
THAT IS LIE OF THE YEAR.
>> Bob: THE BECKEL ALMANAC
SETTLES ALL THE ISSUES.
>> Andrea: THEY DEBUNKED
POLTIFACT A NUMBER OF TIMES.
FOR THEM TO COME OUT AND GIVE
AN AWARD IS OPINION
JOURNALISM.
>> Bob: WE GOT TO GO.
>> Greg: WE HAVE TO MOVE ON.
COMING UP, DID YOU KNOW THE
GOVERNMENT HAS THE POWER TO
FIND OUT ANYTHING THEY WANT
ABOUT YOU?
MAYBE THEY'LL GET ME A NEED
CHRISTMAS PRESENT.
I LIKE HUMMEL.
STICK AROUND.
♪
>> Dana: ALL RIGHT.
WE KNOW SANTA HAS GOT HIS
LIST.
APPARENTLY SO DOES THE
GOVERNMENT!
IT DOESN'T MATTER IF YOU'RE
NAUGHTY OR NICE UNDER THE
GUIDELINES SIGNED BY THE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION LAST SPRING.
THE NATIONAL COUNTERTERRORISM
CENTER CAN NOW COLLECT
INFORMATION ABOUT ANY
U.S. CITIZEN, WITHOUT ANY
REASON OR CAUSE IN THE NAME OF
COUNTERTERRORISM.
WE'RE LEARNING ABOUT THIS,
MORE ABOUT THIS NOW BECAUSE
JULIE ANDWIN OF THE "WALL
STREET JOURNAL" DID A FREEDOM
OF INFORMATION REQUEST TO FIND
OUT WAS THERE EVEN A DEBATE
MOST THE ADMINISTRATION ABOUT
WHETHER OR NOT IT WOULD BE
ALLOWED TO TAKE ANY GOVERNMENT
FILE, SO ANYTIME YOU HAVE THE
GOVERNMENT IF YOUR LIFE, NOW
THAT FILE COULD GO TO NATIONAL
COUNTERTERRORISM CENTER, FOR
ANY REASON.
ARE YOU COMFORTABLE WITH THAT?
>> Greg: WELL, I LIKE, I
MEAN, I HAPPEN TO ENJOY
SURVEILLANCE BUT FOR REASONS I
CAN'T GET IN TO HERE.
GIVING ERIC HOLDER ACCESS IS
GIVING CAR KEYS TO A
KINDERGARTEN GLASS.
WHY DO I FEEL LIKE SHE WILL BE
THE GROUND GAME IN 2016?
WE HAVE IMPRISONED A
FILMMAKER, EXPANDED
SURVEILLANCE OVER AMERICA AND
USED DRONES TO KILL AMERICANS.
WE PAINTED THE RIGHT BEING
THOSE WHO INFRINGE ON RIGHT.
BUT EVIL IS DONE IN NAME OF
AMERICA.
>> Eric: AL-AWLAKI BECAME A
U.S. CITIZEN --
>> I'M OKAY WITH IT.
HE'S A TERRORIST.
IT'S BAD UNDER BUSH AND OKAY
UNDER BAM.
THE THING I LIST ARE OKAY BUT
IF IT WAS --
>> THE TERRORIST SURVEILLANCE
PROGRAM, BROKE BY THE "NEW
YORK TIMES."
PROGRAM IN PLACE TO SURVEIL
ANYONE TALKING TO A TERRORIST
OVERSEAS.
THIS WAS THE BIGGEST DEAL
GOING.
EVERYBODY FREAKED OUT.
RUINED A WAY TO COLLECTER
THOR.
BUT IN ADDITION PROGRAM
ANALYSIS, THEY ADMIT THEY HAVE
TO SO MUCH INFORMATION THEY
DON'T KNOW WHAT TO DO WITH IT.
>> A BIG DIFFERENCE HERE.
PEOPLE ON THE LEFT, WHAT ABOUT
THE PATRIOT ACT.
SIMILAR TYPE OF THINGS.
PAYRY YOT ACT WENT THROUGH
CONGRESS AND VOTED ON.
THEY WANT TO PULL IT, THEY CAN
PULL THE PLUG ON IT.
THIS IS EXECUTIVE ORDER.
IT HAPPENED BEHIND CLOSED
DOORS.
THE "WALL STREET JOURNAL" DID
A REQUEST BUT THIS VIOLATES
THE FOURTH AMENDMENT.
THEY CAN GO IN AND TAKE WHAT
THEY WANT WITHOUT THE PROBABLE
CAUSE.
THEY DON'T TO PROVE PROBABLE
THIS IS DISTURBING.
>> THIS IS AND OUGHT TO BE
DONE AWAY WITH.
THE REASON YOU SIGN THE
EXECUTIVE ORDER IS BECAUSE OF
THE PATRIOT ACT.
IT GIVES THE PRESIDENT THE
AUTHORITY IN ADMINISTRATION --
>> THAT IS --
>> EXECUTIVE ORDER ON THIS
PART.
YOU COULDN'T BEFORE THE
PATRIOT ACT YOU COULDN'T SIGN
A THING.
BUT WHAT YOU TALK ABOUT,
REMEMBER THE PHONE COMPANIES
GOT IN THAT IS ALL OF THAT
TROUBLE, THEY HELPED OUT THE
ADMINISTRATION IN
COUNTERTERRORISM AND PULLED
THE PLUG ON THAT.
TERRIBLE.
>> Andrea: THE PATRIOT ACT
WAS DESIGNED TO FOCUS ON
TERRORISM.
THE BUSH ADMINISTRATION USED
IT TO GET TERRORISM
INFORMATION NON-TERRORISM DATA
BASES.
THIS IS TO GET ANY INFORMATION
ANYWHERE.
NOT JUST THE FOURTH AMENDMENT.
FRONT TO THE BILL OF RIGHTS.
YOU KNOW, THOUGH, THE LEFT HAS
BEEN SESELECTIVELY BERSERK
ABOUT PRIVACY.
THEY HAVE BEEN TRYING TO GET
HANDS ON THE MEDICAL RECORDS
FOR YEARS.
THEY ARE DOING IT UNDER
OBAMACARE.
AS YOU POINT OUT, AS LONG AS
IT'S FOR THE GREATER GOOD,
PRIVACY DOESN'T MATTER.
THEY CAN DO WHATEVER THEY
WANT.
I HOPE IT HEADS TO THE COURTS.
I CAN'T EVEN BELIEVE THEY
FOCUS ON TERRORISM.
>> THE ADMINISTRATION, THEY
SAY THEY ONLY LOOK AT LIKELY
TERRORISM THINGS.
MORE INFORMATION IS NEEDED.
IN SAN FRANCISCO AND THE OTHER
CITIES, SOME OF THE PUBLIC BUS
SYSTEMS PUT MICROPHONE IN THE
SEAT TO DO SURVEILLANCE.
IMAGINE IF YOU HEARD THIS
CONVERSATION.
THERE IS GREG, BOB, ERIC,
IMAGINE YOU WERE ON A PUBLIC
BUS AND HEAR WHAT THEY WERE
TALKING ABOUT.
>> THAT IS FUNNY.
>> Greg: I HAVE NEVER BEEN
ON A PUBLIC BUS.
THE ONLY TALK YOU HEAR ON A
BUS IS A GUY HAVING A
CONVERSATION WITH HIMSELF.
HE'S NORMALLY NOT WEARING
PANTS.
BUT ENOUGH ABOUT BILL HEMMER.
>> Andrea: BILL DOESN'T RIDE
THE BUS.
>> Bob: I TALK TO A NUMBER
OF LIBERAL SINCE THE STORY
BROKE.
THEY ARE ALL FURIOUS ABOUT IT.
THIS IS NOT THE LIBERALS
BEHIND THIS.
THEY ARE OUTRAGED.
>> Dana: THE WAY THEY DEAL
WITH THE ORDERS AND THE RULE
MAKING THEY PUT THEM UP ON A
WEBSITE.
AS IF IT'S OUR RESPONSIBILITY
TO GO TO THE WEBSITE AND CHECK
OUT THE RULES.
WHERE IS THE PRESS?
SIX MONTHS LATER SHE WROTE
THIS.
NINTHS LATER.
WHERE ARE THE --
>> Eric: I'M OKAY WITH IT.
I'M FINE WITH PUTTING
SURVEILLANCE ON BUSES.
>> Greg: WHAT?
>> Eric: LISTEN, I'M ALL FOR
PUTTING SURVEILLANCE ON THE
SCHOOL BUSS TO FIND OUT IF
KIDS ARE BEING BEATING YOU
KNOW WHAT OUT OF EACH OTHER.
>> Andrea: YOUR POINT IS THE
LIBERALS ARE NOT IN FAVOR OF
WHAT THE OBAMA ADMINISTRATION
IS DOING.
I HAVEN'T HEARD THE OUTRAGE
THAT WE HEARD IN THE BUSH
ADMINISTRATION.
>> Bob: YOU WON'T HEAR THE
SAME LEVEL OF OUTRAGE
OBVIOUSLY BUT THERE ARE PEOPLE
OUTRAGED BY IT.
LEVIN IN THE SENATE WILL MAKE
A STINK ABOUT IT.
>> Andrea: IF THEY'RE
OUTRAGED IT MUST BE A WHISPER.
>> Eric: THE DIFFERENCE HERE
IS THE PUBLIC BUS.
>> Dana: NOT JUST SCHOOL
BUS.
ANY BUS.
>> Greg: PRIVATIZE BUSES.
DABS YOU WANT OUTRAGE?
COMING UP.
BARBARA WALTERS PICKS THE
FASCINATING PERSON OF THE
YEAR, WITH STIFF COMPETITION
LIKE HONEY BOO-BOO AND THE
BEEN A ONE DIRECTION.
IF YOU LEAVE NOW YOU WON'T
FIND OUT WHY THEY WROTE THIS
SONG ABOUT ERIC BOLLING.
♪
NOW HAVE BACK TO FORK AND MY
COLLEAGUES WITH "THE FIVE."
♪
>> Andrea: WELCOME BACK TO
"THE FIVE."
BARBARA WALTERS REVEALED HER
MOST FASCINATING PERSON PICKED
LAST NIGHT.
WE'LL TELL YOU OUR THOUGHTS IN
A MOMENT.
BUT FIRST, THE LIST INSPIRED
ME ALONG WITH "TIME" MAGAZINE
UPCOMING PERSON OF THE YEAR
NAMING TO HIT THE STREETS TO
ASK AMERICANS WHO THEY THINK
DESERVES THE TITLE.
WHO DO YOU THINK SHOULD BE
PERSON OF THE YEAR?
>> HARRY FROM ONE DIRECTION.
>> ELI MANNING.
>> THE PRESIDENT.
>> I THINK MITT ROMNEY.
I THINK.
I MEAN IT'S HARD TO BE THE
RUNNER UP.
>> SANTA CLAUS.
>> GOOD ONE!
>> SANTA CLAUS IS THE PERSON
OF THE YEAR.
>> DO YOU KNOW THAT A
4-YEAR-OLD JUST GAVE ME THAT
EXACT SAMENANCE
>> GREAT MINDSAMENANCE -- SAME
ANSWER.
>> GREAT MINDS THINK ALIKE.
>> Andrea: SOMEONE SAID I
SHOULD BE PERSON OF THE YEAR
FOR PUTTING UP WITH YOU.
LAST NIGHT, BARBARA WALTERS
WENT DOWN HER LIST OF
FASCINATING PEOPLE.
BEN AFFLECK, GREG CAN MAKE A
LOT OF MOVIES AND HAVE THEM
BOMB AND YOU'RE STILL
CONSIDERED FASCINATING.
THE AUTHOR OF "50 SHADES OF
GRAY."
ONE DIRECTION.
PRINCE MAR HARRY AND SHE PUT CHS
CHRISTIE ON HER LIST.
LAST NIGHT SHE ASKED HIM, THIS
IS ONE OF THE REASONS WHY I
LOVE BARBER WALTERS.
SHE HAD GUTS TO ASK A QUESTION
A LOT OF PEOPLE HAVE BEEN
TALKING ABOUT.
HIS WEIGHT.
>> THERE ARE PEOPLE THAT SAY
YOU COULDN'T BE PRESIDENT
BECAUSE YOU ARE SO HEAVY.
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THAT?
>> THAT IS RIDICULOUS.
PEOPLE WATCHED ME FOR SEVERAL
WEEKS IN HURRICANE SANDY DOING
18-HOUR DAYS SO I DON'T THINK
IT WOULD BE A PROBLEM.
>> Andrea: WHAT DO YOU
THINK?
>> Greg: WHAT A WEAK, WEAK
QUESTION.
THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO SAY --
BARBARA, WHO SAID IT?
IT WAS YOU WHO SAID IT.
SHE SAID I THINK YOU'RE FAT.
I THINK YOU'RE FAT.
THAT IS WHAT YOU SHOULD HAVE
SAID.
"THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO SAY --"
WHAT A WUSSY QUESTION.
>> Andrea: A LOT OF PEOPLE
THINK THAT.
A LOT OF PEOPLE TALK ABOUT
THAT.
>> Greg: WHO?
>> Andrea: ME AND MY
FRIENDS.
WE DO.
>> Bob: THEY SAY --
>> Greg: YEAH, THEY SAY.
SOME SAY.
>> Andrea: ALL RIGHT.
HERE IS ANOTHER EXAMPLE OF
SOMETHING THAT -- THIS IS
SOMETHING I THINK ABOUT.
HILLARY CLINTONN FRONT OF
HER.
LISTEN TO THIS.
SHE ASKED A QUESTION ABOUT
HILLARY CLINTON'S HAIR.
SOMETHING WE ALL THINK ABOUT.
>> YOUR HAIR.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> I KNOW IT IS ONE OF THE
GREAT FASCINATIONS OF OUR TIME
MUCH TO MY AMAZEMENT.
>> I DO NOT TRAVEL A HAIR
DRESSER AND I'M NOT VERY
COMPETENT MYSELF.
I HAVE BEEN ADMITTING THAT FOR
YEARS WHICH SHOULD BE OBVIOUS
TO EVERYONE.
SO I SAID ENOUGH, WE'RE JUST
GOING TO TRY TO GO WITH SIMPLE
AS POSSIBLE.
>> Bob: SOMEBODY EXPLAIN TO
ME WHO IS THIS BAND THING?
I NEVER HEARD OF THEM.
SHE PUT HONEY GOO BOO?
>> HONEY BOO-BOO.
>> Bob: THAT CHICK GETS MORE
PUBLICITY FOR DOING NOTHING.
>> Eric: R.C. COLA AND MOON
PIE.
IT'S MOST FASCINATING.
>> Bob: YOU FIND HER
FASCINATING?
>> Eric: I DO.
IF WE TALK ABOUT AND PEOPLE
WAND -- PEOPLE WHO WATCH ARE
DISGUSTED.
OTHER HALF ARE ENAR MOREED.
THAT IS FASCINATING.
BOBS OF THAT KID?
>> Eric: YEAH.
>> Bob: REALLY.
>> Eric: THAT KID.
>> Bob: WHO IS THE BAND?
>> Andrea: BOY BAND.
>> Dana: LIKE YOUR DAUGHTER
PROBABLY LIKES THEM.
SHE MIGHT BE TOO OLD.
>> Greg: YOU HAVE A ONE
DIRECTION LUNCHPAIL.
>> Dana: I HAVE ONE FOR
EVERY DAY OF THE WEEK.
MONDAY THROUGH FRIDAY.
IT ALWAYS BRING MY LUNCH.
WELL-BALANCED MEAL WITH BABY
CARROTS.
>> Andrea: DANA, WHAT DO YOU
THINK OF THE LIST?
>> Dana: I LIKE HILLARY
CLINTON.
THAT WAS GOOD.
I THINK BILL CLINTON WAS
PRETTY FASCINATING THIS YEAR.
HE CAME BACK FROM KIND OF
HADN'T BEEN IN PUBLIC EYE MUCH
TO HELP BARACK OBAMA WIN
AGAIN.
I THOUGHT IT WAS WEIRD -- I
WOULD HAVE PUT BLAKE SHELTON
ON THE LIST.
>> Greg: PLEASE!
>> Dana: THERE IS A GOOD
REASON.
YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW.
>> Bob: WHO IS THE NUMBER
ONE?
>> Andrea: NUMBER ONE IS
DAVID PETRAEUS.
I ACTUALLY, I AGREE WITH THAT.
>> Bob: DANA MADE A GOOD
POINT.
WHAT HAS DAVID PETRAEUS DONE
THIS YEAR?
EXCEPT GET IN AN AFFAIR.
>> Greg: TWO HE'S DONE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
WHO USES THE WORD
"FASCINATING" WHEN THEY
DESCRIBE SOMEBODY --
>> Dana: TALK ABOUT YOU ALL
THE TIME.
>> Greg: ASIDE FROM ME.
YOU HAVE DON'T GO I JUST RAN
IN TO THE MOST FASCINATING
PERSON.
NO PLANETS ARE FASCINATING.
SCIENTIFIC DISCOVERIES ARE
FASCINATING.
LEMUR, FASCINATING.
PEOPLE, NOT FASCINATING.
PEOPLE ARE PEOPLE.
>> Dana: I DIDN'T HAVE TIME.
FOLLOW ME ON TWITTER TONIGHT
AS I GO TO VEGAS FOR THE
NATIONAL FINAL RODEO.
IT WILL TELL YOU WHY I THINK
BLAKE SHELTON SHOULD HAVE BEEN
ON THE LIST.
THERE IS A GOOD REASON.
NOT JUST BECAUSE HE IS A GOOD
SINGER.
>> Bob: CAN I HAVE A PHRASE
BANNED?
"TO DIE FOR."
>> Greg: OKAY.
>> Bob: WHO SAID THAT?
IT CAME IN MY MIND.
>> Eric: YOU COULD BE ONE OF
THE MOST FASCINATING PEOPLE I
KNOW.
>> Andrea: ON THAT NOTE, YOU
ARE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
BOB, YOU MIGHT JUST BE THE
MOST FASCINATING PERSON.
AT LEAST HERE AT "THE FIVE."
>> Bob: THEY BROKE THE MOLD,
I GUESS.
>> Andrea: THEY DID.
COMING UP.
A MAN SUES A STRIP CLUB AFTER
HE SAYS THE LADIES TOOK
ADVANTAGE OF HIM.
DID THE ARGUMENT HOLD UP IN
COURT?
IT WAS BOB -- SORRY, I MEAN
BOB HAS THE ANSWER.
UP NEXT.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS STEVE.
HE LOVES RISK.
BUT WHETHER
HE'S CLIMBING EVEREST,
SCUBA DIVING THE
GREAT BARRIER REEF WITH SHARKS,
OR JUMPING INTO THE MARKET,
HE GOES WITH PEOPLE HE TRUSTS,
WHICH IS WHY HE TRADES
WITH A COMPANY
THAT DOESN'T NICKEL AND DIME
HIM WITH HIDDEN FEES.
SO HE CAN WORRY
ABOUT OTHER THINGS,
LIKE WHAT THE MARKET IS DOING
AND BEING READY,
NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENS,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE,
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
TIRED OF FEES PILING UP
INTRODUCING CHASE LIQUID.
THE RELOADABLE CARD
WITH NO FEE RELOADS
AND WITHDRAWALS AT CHASE ATMS.
ALL FOR ONE FLAT MONTHLY FEE
SO THERE'S ZERO CONFUSION.
GET RID OF PREPAID PROBLEMS.
GET CHASE LIQUID.
♪
>> Bob: YOU GOT TO LOVE
RICKY NELSON.
FIRST, WHY DO I GET THIS
SEGMENT?
HERE IS THE WAY THE PRODUCERS
SAID IT TO ME.
BOB, WHEN YOU COME UP WITH THE
STORY, PLEASE TRY TO KEEP IT
CLASSY.
THIS IS A STORY ABOUT
SOMETHING I KNOW A LITTLE BIT
ABOUT, A STRIP JUMP.
LARRY FLINT'S HUSTLER CLUB.
A GUY BY THE NAME OF WILLIAM
RANED UP A BILL OF $28,000, HE
CLAIMS BECAUSE THE WAITRESSES
WHICH HAPPENS IN THESE PLACES,
HELP HIM RUN UP THE BILL AND
SUED THE CLUB TO GET THE MONEY
BACK.
HE SAID HE WAS TOO DRUNK,
INCAPACITATED.
THE JUDGE THREW IT OUT.
IF I COULD HAVE SUED FOR EVERY
BIT OF MONEY I LEFT AT A BAR,
I'D BE -- IT'S WORK.
RIDICULOUS CONCEPT.
THE GUY, IF YOU CAN'T HANDLE
IT, BUDDY.
GET OUT.
YOU KNOW?
WHAT DO YOU THINK THE WOMEN
ARE THERE FOR?
THEY ARE THERE TO PUSH DRINKS
ON YOU.
>> Dana: CAN I ASK YOU
SOMETHING.
IS IT POSSIBLE TO ORDER
$28,000 WORTH OF DRINKS AT A
CLUB LIKE THAT?
>> Bob: YEAH.
>> Andrea: I'M SURPRISED
IT'S SO LITTLE.
EVERY SIX MONTHS THERE IS A
STORY ABOUT SOMEONE WHO GOES
IN ONE OF THE MANLY, MECCAS
AND I PULLED UP THE NUMBERS.
$241,000 AT FLASH DANCERS.
ANOTHER GUY SPENT $47,000.
>> Dana: ONE NIGHT?
>> Bob: THAT WAS TIPS.
>> Andrea: LAP DANCING AND
OTHER ACTIVITY.
>> Bob: DO YOU KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT LAP DANCING?
>> Eric: NO BUT I KNOW
SOMETHING ABOUT BOTTLE SERVICE
IN NIGHTCLUBS.
$500 A BOTTLE FOR VODKA AND DO
THE MATH.
YOU COULD RUNG UP THE BILLS.
THE NEW HOT CHAMPAGNE, ACE OF
SPADES, AND I THINK JAY-Z
MIGHT BE -- HE HAS SOME PIECE
OF THAT ACTION.
$500 A BOTTLE.
POPPING THEM LEFT AND RIGHT.
>> Bob: DID YOU GO TO TRIP
CLUBS AND RUN UP BAR TABS?
>> Greg: I STRIPPED FOR A
WHILE TO GET THROUGH DENTAL
COLLEGE AND WE SEE VERY LITTLE
MONEY FROM THE DOOR.
IT WAS A HARROWING EXPERIENCE.
IF YOU HAVE SEEN "MAGIC MIKE"
IT'S BASED ON MY LIFE.
THE WORST THING ABOUT THE
STRIP CLUB, THOUGH, NOT THE
PRICES, THE FREE BUT FAYE.
ONLY THING FREE ABOUT THE
BUFFET IS HEPATITIS.
>> Bob: THE MONEY THEY
CHARGE FOR DRINKS IN THE
PLACES ARE LIKE $20 A POP.
>> Greg: IT'S A DEPRESSING
PLACE.
THE WOMEN DO NOT LIKE YOU.
YOU GO IN AND WHEN YOU LEAVE,
YOU ARE THE SAME SCHMUCK AS
WHEN YOU WENT IN THERE.
>> Bob: THEY HAVE KNIVES AND
CUT YOU APART.
>> Andrea: YOU NEVER A WOMAN
MAKING THIS MISTAKE IN A MALE
STRIP CLUB.
>> Bob: SURE YOU DO.
>> Andrea: C'MON.
$28,000?
WOMAN SAYS I GOT TOO DRUNK, I
COULDN'T SAY NO?
CHIPPENDALES?
>> Eric: THE REASON I KNOW
THESE NUMBERS IS NOT BECAUSE
OF STRIP CLUBS.
IT'S REGULAR NIGHTCLUBS.
I WANT TO BE CLEAR.
NOT THE STRIP KIND.
>> Bob: COVER UP FOR YOUR
WIFE HERE.
YOU SAY YOU HAVE NEVER BEEN TO
A STRIP CLUB.
>> Eric: SHE KNOWS I HAVE
GONE A STRIP CLUB.
>> Bob: ONE MORE THING IS
NEXT.
DIDN'T GET YOU.
♪
>> Eric: ALL RIGHT.
TIME FOR ONE FOR THING.
DANA IS KICKING IT OFF.
>> Dana: ONE OF THE GREAT
SENATOR OF THE UNITED STATES,
SENATOR JOE LIEBERMAN OF
CONNECTICUT GAVET
SPEECH AS A SENATOR ON
SATURDAY.
TAKE A LISTEN TO THIS.
>> MR. PRESIDENT, MY FOURTH
AND FINAL TERM AS THE UNITED
STATES SENATOR WILL SOON COME
TO AN END.
AS I REFLECT ON THAT REALITY,
I AM OF COURSE FILLED WITH
MANY EMOTIONS.
BUT THE ONE THAT I FEEL MOST
IS GRATITUDE.
I LEAVE THIS CHAMBER AS FULL
OF FAITH AND THE DREAM CALLED
AMERICA.
AS WHEN I STOOD HERE NEAR A
QUARTER CENTURY AGO TO TAKE
THE OATH OF OFFICE FOR THE
FIRST TIME.
THANK YOU, ALL.
I HAVE A LOT TO BE GRATEFUL
FOR.
>> Dana: HE IS A VERY
HONORABLE MAN.
WONDERFUL UNITED STATES
SENATOR.
I THINK HE WILL GO DOWN WELL
IN HISTORY AND EXCITING TO SEE
WHAT HE DOES NEXT.
THANK, SENATOR LIEBERMAN FOR
ALL YOU DID.
>> Eric: THANK YOU, SIR, AS
WELL.
ANDREA, YOU'RE UP.
>> Andrea: THE OTHER DAY I
WAS IN MY KITCHEN AND WATCHING
A MOVIE WHILE I'M COOKING AND
IT GOES TO COMMERCIAL BREAK
AND THE COMMERCIAL WAS SO LOUD
I JUMPED.
BUT GUESS WHAT?
STARTING TODAY.
NO MORE.
CONGRESS HAS DONE SOMETHING
POSITIVE WITH THEIR TIME.
THEY PASSED A LAW MAKING IT
ILLEGAL I GUESS FOR
ADVERTISERS TO RAISE THE
VOLUME ON COMMERCIALS ABOVE
TWO DECIBELS, SO NO MORE LOUD
COMMERCIALS.
THANK CONGRESS FOR GETTING
SOMETHING DONE.
I THINK BOTH SIDES CAN AGREE
ON.
>> Bob: COULD WE GET IT DONE
HERE?
>> Andrea: YOU ARE THE ONE
SPEAKING LOUDEST.
>> Bob: YOU WERE COOKING?
WERE YOU A BIG COOK?
>> Andrea: I WAS MAKING
SOUP.
BOEHNER PASS YOUR BILL TODAY.
GET THE GUYS ON THE RECORD
BEFORE YOU LEAVE.
BRING SOMETHING TO THE FLOOR.
DON'T WAIT FOR THE WHITE
HOUSE.
>> Eric: LET'S MOVE ON.
START WITH THIS.
WE HAVE DIDN'T GET A CHANCE
BECAUSE OF THE BREAKING NEWS
TO TALK ABOUT THIS BUT WE
WOULD LIKE TO GET IN THE SHOW
TOMORROW.
JOHN HAMMER, ALWAYS A MARINE,
IMPRISON IN MEXICO FOR
CARRYING A SHOTGUN OVER THE
BORDER AND AD HELD DOWN IN
CHAUNCE.
LET'S GET HIM FREED.
TAKE A DIP IN RIGHT NOW TO THE
NEGOTIATIONS OVER THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
BOEHNER AND OBAMA SEE HOW IT'S
GOING.
CAN WE SEE IT?
I'M JUST KIDDING.
THAT IS UKRAINE PARLIAMENT
HANDLING THINGS THE WAY,
PROBABLY THE WAY IT SHOULD BE
DONE.
THAT'S IT.
BOB, YOU'RE UP.
>> Bob: I THOUGHT THAT WAS
THE REPUBLICAN HOUSE CAUCUS.
>> Greg: UNIONS.
>> Bob: OF COURSE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
THERE IS A GUY BY THE NAME OF
JOE LUKEN IN MINNESOTA.
HE OWNS LEGISRY STORES AND A
BIG MARKET CHAIN THAT WANTED
TO BUY HIS STORES WHEN HE PUT
THEM UP FOR SALE AND HE
DECIDED INSTEAD OF DOING THAT
HE WOULD TURN THEM OVER, ALL
OF THEM TO THE EMPLOYEES, 400
OF THEM.
AND KIO PLAN BECAUSE WITHOUT
THEM HE NEVER WOULD HAVE BEEN
SUCCESSFUL.
CONGRATULATE HIM FOR DOING
THAT, PARTICULARLY IN THE
CHRISTMAS SEASON.
WONDERFUL GESTURE ON YOUR
PART, JOE, AND YOUR EMPLOYEES
WILL CARRY ON TO MAKE MORE
SUCCESS OUT OF THE STORES.
NICE THING TO DO.
>> Eric: GREGORY?
>> Greg: FIRST, I'LL READ
THE HOROSCOPE.
SOMETIMES IT'S SMART TO LET
YOUR RIVALS WIN AND THIS COULD
BE ONE OF THOSE OCCASIONS.
UNTIE THE ARMENIAN MAN FROM
THE BASEMENT RADIATOR.
WOW!
WRANGLER, TOMORROW, RIGHT?
YOU'RE LEAVING.
DANA IS GOING TO THE WRANGLER
NATIONAL FINALS RODEO THAT
INVOLVES HORSES TAKING FINALS.
CORRECT?
>> Dana: LIKE TESTS?
>> Greg: YES.
>> Dana: NO.
>> Greg: IT'S IN LAS VEGAS.
SHE IS LEAVING TOMORROW.
BUT THE GOOD NEWS IS YOU WILL
BE REPORTING FROM THE RODEO
FOR "THE FIVE."
>> Dana: ARE YOU BRINGING
THAT GIRL BACK AGAIN?
THERE IS A NEW GIRL, A NEW
RODEO QUEEN.
>> Bob: GET HER PHONE
NUMBER.
>> Dana: I'LL SEE WHAT I CAN
DO.