FROM THE PEOPLE AT RIPLEY'S, A
SPOKESMAN SAYS THE COMPANY IS
OFFERING FREE ADMISSION TO ALL
OF THE GALLERIES ON SATURDAY
DECEMBER 22ND.
BUT THIS IS A CATCH, THE OFFER
IS GOOD ONLY IF THE WORLD ENDS
ON FRIDAY 21st.
THE SPOKESMAN SAYS VISITERS WHO
PROVIDE PROOF OF THE WORLD END
WALK RIGHT IN NO CHARGE.
NO DOUBT THE BOSSES AT RIPLEY
HOPE THEY GET FREE PUBLICITY
LIKE THIS AND BRING IN NEW
PAYING CUSTOMERS.
HOPEFULLY THAT WON'T WORK.
THIS IS IT FOR "STUDIO B" TODAY.
THE DOW IS UP IN A BIG WAY AT
110 POINTS.
NEIL CAVUTO IS HERE FOR CONTEXT
AND I WILL SEE YOU TONIGHT.
>>Neil: REPUBLICANS PUT THE
BIG GUY ON THE SPOT.
YOU DON'T GET US OFF THIS CLIFF
WE WILL.
THEY PROPOSING A BACKUP PLAN
CANCELING TAX INCREASES DUE TO
HIT IN TWO WEEKS ON EVERYONE
EARNING LESS THAN $1 MILLION AND
THE SPEAKER BOEHNER SAYS HE IS
RAISING EVEN MORE REVENUE THAN
HE FIRST PROPOSED PUTTING IT NOW
ON THE PRESIDENT WOULD HAS TO
COME UP WITH SPENDING CUTS.
FAST.
WELCOME, EVERYONE, I AM NEIL
CAVUTO.
THEY ARE GET CLOSE BUT STILL IN
DEAL.
REPUBLICANS WANT TO MAKE CLEAR
THAT IF THEY DON'T GET A DEAL IT
AIN'T OR FAULT.
THEY HIKED TAXES MORE THAN THEY
WANTED WAITING FOR DEMOCRATS
THEY SAY WHO HAVE NOT DELIVERED
ANY SPENDING CUTS THEY PROMISED.
NO WORD ON THAT.
TO CAPITOL HILL SENIOR PRODUCER
ON HOW ALL OF THIS IS GOING
DOWN.
THAT IS THE LATEST?
>>Reporter: WE ARE TOLD IN
THE PAST COUPLE OF MINUTES THAT
AN OFFICIAL TELLS ED HENRY IT IS
WORST IN THE PAST 24 HOURS.
THEY FELT THEY TOOK A STEP BACK
BECAUSE OF PLAN (B) THAT SPEAKER
BOEHNER IS PROPOSING TO THE
CONFERENCE MEETING IN CLOSED
CONFERENCE IN LESS THAN AN HOUR,
FOR SHOW THEM WHAT THE PLAN IS.
WE UNDERSTAND THEY WILL HAVE TWO
VOTES, PROBABLY THURSDAY, ONE
WOULD RENEW ALL SO-CALLED BUSH
TAX CUTS FOR THOSE MAKING LESS
THAN $1 MILLION A YEAR SO
REPUBLICANS CAN SAY, WELL, WE
DIDN'T VOTE TO RAISE TAXES.
THERE WILL BE A SECOND VOTE TO
RENEW ALL OF THE TAX CUTS FOR
THOSE MAKING LESS THAN $200,000
A YEAR OR COUPLES UP TO $250,000
A YEAR.
THAT IS INTERESTING HERE, THEY
ARE TRYING TO CALL THE
DEMOCRATS' BLUFF.
SPEAKER BOEHNER THINKS HE CAN
MUSCLE THIS THROUGH THE HOUSE
BECAUSE THEY ARE NOT RAISING
TAXES.
THERE IS NOT A VOTE WHERE PEOPLE
CAN SAY YOU VOTED TO RAISE TAXES
BUT OUTSIDE GROUPS MAY NOT SEE
IT THAT WAY.
THEY ARE GOING TO POINT, THE
REPUBLICS ARE GOING TO POINT, TO
A LETTER THAT HOUSE MINORITY
LEADER NANCY PELOSI SENT TO THE
SPEAKER BACK IN MAY SAYING WE
THINK YOU SHOULD RAISE TAXES ON
THOSE WHO MAKE MORE THAN $1
MILLION A YEAR FOR BRING IN MORE
REVENUE.
IT IS A GAME OF CHICKEN.
THEY WOULD KICK THIS OVER TO THE
SENATE.
THE PROBLEM IN THE NOT IS
McCONNELL, THE MINORITY LEADER
THERE, SAID HE WOULD TAKE A LOOK
AT THE PROPOSAL.
IN HIS REMARKS HE SAID I DON'T
WANT TO RAISE TAXES ON ANYONE
BUT I WANT TO PROVIDE TAX BREAKS
FOR AS MANY PEOPLE AS POSSIBLE.
SO THIS IS GETTING VERY SHAKY.
>>Neil: WE HAVE HEARD THE
WHITE HOUSE MOVE ON THEIR
FIGURES FROM $250,000 AND OVER
AFTER THE $1 MILLION OFFER BY
THE SPEAK THEY SAID $400,000.
WHAT ARE FOLKS TELLING YOU THEY
WILL LIKELY SETTLE ON UPPER
INCOME TAX?
>>Guest: WE HEAR THERE COULD
BE A THIRD VOTE, PERHAPS, ON THE
$400,000 OR SOME OTHER LEVEL
THAT IS SOMETHING THAT IS UP IN
THE AIR THAT IS FAR FROM BEING
IN CONCRETE.
THEY IS TO GET REPUBLICANS FULLY
ON BOARD.
A REPUBLICAN FRESHMAN
CONGRESSMAN FROM IDAHO SAYS THIS
IS A TERRIBLE IDEA FOR MULTIPLE
REASONS.
ANOTHER FROM OHIO THE MOST
CONSERVATIVE MEMBER OF THE HOUSE
OF REPRESENTATIVES SAYS I AM NOT
DOING CARTWHEELS OVER THIS AND
PEOPLE HAVE TO HEAR WHAT THIS
SOUNDS LIKE WHEN IT IS LAID OUT
IN THE CONFERENCE IN AN HOUR AND
START TO HEAR FROM THE LOBBY
GROUPS.
THAT IS GOING TO BE VERY TOUCHY.
SOME MEMBERS ARE NUT DANCING IN
THE STREETS.
SOMETIMES THE BILLS, THE OFFERS,
WHEN YOU GET TO THE NITTY-GRITTY
HAVE TO FAIL AND MAYBE THAT HAS
TO HAPPEN.
I TALKED OF THE TROUBLED ASSET
RELIEF PROGRAM IN 2008 THAT
FAILED IN THE HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES, IT NEEDED TO
FAIL BEFORE IT PASSED.
>>Neil: BOTH WERE MEANT TO
PLACATE WALL STREET AFTER WALL
STREET FELL ALMOST 800 POINTS
WOULD FALL AFTER THEY APPROVED
TARP II.
IF WE GET UP TO CHRISTMAS
HOLIDAYS AND NEW YEAR HOLIDAY
ALL THE USUAL TRADERS THE NOT BE
ON WALL STREET, SO TO HAVE A
REMARKABLE MARKET FLUCTUATION
COULD BE MORE IN THE CARDS, YOU
COULD HAVE SOMETHING THAT IS
MORE ERRATIC THAN DURING THE
FAILED TARP VOTE.
SOME THINK A MARKET REACTION IS
REALLY WHAT HAS TO HAPPEN TO
FORCE A DEAL THE FACT THAT NO
ONE CAN MOVE AND GET TO 218
VOTES IN THE HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES AND 51 VOTES IN
THE SENATE WITH A RADICAL MARKET
REACTION THAT GETS PEOPLES'
ATTENTION AND WE ARE NOT THERE
YET.
PEOPLE ARE NUT THERE.
>>Neil: THE TARGET OF TAX
HIKES COULD BE CHANGING, THE
TALK OF TAX HIKES IS NOT OF THE
THAT IS THE PROBLEM.
YOU ARGUE, PHIL, TOO MUCH
OBSESSING HOW FAR THE TAXES GO
UP AND NOT ABOUT HOW MUCH
SPENDING GOES DOWN IF AT ALL.
>>Guest: IT IS QUITE OBVIOUS
TO ANYONE THAT STUDIES THE
MATTER, WASHINGTON HAS A
SPENDING PROBLEM.
NOT A REVENUE PROBLEM.
IF YOU LOOK AT RAIDING TAXES ON
MILLIONAIRES, PRESIDENT OBAMA
CAMPAIGNED ON INCREASING TAXES
ON THE MILLIONAIRES AND
BILLIONAIRES SO NOW IF YOU MAKE
$200,000 YOU ARE A MILLIONAIRE
OR A BILLIONAIRE.
EVEN IF YOU DO THAT THE REVENUE
YOU GAIN IF THAT IS NOT GOING TO
GET US OUT OF THE PROBLEMS.
SO HERE IN THE REAL WORLD THERE
IS NOT A LOT HOPE THAT ANYTHING
THAT REACHES, COMES CLOSE TO
SANITY WILL TAKE PLACE IN
WASHINGTON.
>>Neil: WHAT DO YOU THINK OF
THE VOTE AMONG THE REPUBLICAN
CAUCUS ON THE TAX HIKES, TO
MILLIONAIRES IN THIS CASE?
ANYONE WHO VOTES FOR THAT, DO
YOU REMEMBER OR DO YOU VOW
RETRIBUTION?
>>Guest: THE FEELING WITH MOST
TEA PARTY MEMBERS ACROSS
COUNTRY, THERE ARE 43 MILLION OF
US, THE ONLY PEOPLE THAT LIKE US
LESS THAN THE DEMOCRATS ARE THE
REPUBLICANS.
WE SAY WHAT BOEHNER DID WITH THE
COMMITTEE CHAIRS THAT HELD FAST
TO TEA PARTY PRINCIPLES.
IN 2014, LOOK, I WAS HERE AFTER
BOEHNER WAS ELECTED SPEAKER IN
2010 WHEN THE REPUBLICANS
RETURNED TO POWER AND WE DIDN'T
HAVE HIGH HOPES FOR THE
REPUBLICANS THEN.
THE FEELING WE HAVE IS THAT NO
ONE IS SERIOUS ABOUT CUTTING
SPENDING IN WASHINGTON, DC.
THEY MAY TRIM AROUND THE EDGES
BUT NO ONE IS SERIOUS.
YOU HAVE BERNANKE PRINTING $80
BILLION A MONTH AND IT IS PHONY.
NO ONE IS SERIOUS.
THE OTHER THING, QUICKLY, THE
NUMBER ONE RULE OF NEGOTIATING
IS DO NOT NEGOTIATE AGAINST
YOURSELF.
SPEAKER BOEHNER HAS BEEN DOING A
GREAT DEAL OF THAT.
IT IS OBVIOUS THAT THE DEMOCRATS
AND PRESIDENT OBAMA ARE NOT
INTERESTED IN MAKING A DEAL SO
LET THEM TAKE IT OVER THE CLIFF.
MOST MACHINES ARE PREPARED FOR
THAT.
>>Neil: WE WILL SEE.
THANK YOU, PHILIP, FROM DALLAS.
>> IF STOCKS ARE PANIC THEY HAD
A FUNNY WAY OF SHOWING IT.
THE DOW WAS IN EXCESS OF 115
POINTS, BET THAN 3 PERCENT IN
THE PAST TWO WEEKS, LARGELY ON
OPTIMISM OF A DEAL.
MY GUEST SAYS THAT IS BECAUSE
REALITY HAS YET TO SINK IN.
NOW, TODD, YOUR ARGUMENT IS
WHATEVER IS BEING CRAFTED HERE
LOOKS LIKE A BAD DEAL.
>>Guest: THAT IS RIGHT.
WALL STREET IS GIVING INVESTORS
EARLY CHRISTMAS PRESENT RIGHT
NOW.
HERE IS THE THING.
EVERYONE ON WALL STREET IS
LOOKING AT HISTORY.
WE HAVE BEEN DOWN THIS ROAD
BEFORE WITH WASHINGTON.
THE NEGOTIATIONS.
THE LAST MINUTE DEALS.
EVERYONE THINKS THAT, YES, WE
WILL HAVE SOME TIME OF
RESOLUTION BEFORE YEAR END.
HOWEVER, THE SMART MONEY OUT
THERE IS PICKING UP ON THIS WE
ARE SO FAR APART, KNOWING IS
GOING TO GET ACCOMPLISHED AND
YOU WILL NEED A MIRACLE TO GET
SOMETHING DONE BY THE END OF THE
YEAR.
LOOK FOR SERIOUS VOLATILITY IN
THE NEXT COUPLE OF WEEKS AS WE
CLOSE THE YEAR.
>>Neil: AND THE BIG PLAYERS
LIKE YOURSELF, AND IN A CASE
WHERE A LOT OF THE BIG CHEESES
ARE NOT AROUND, YOU COULD HAVE A
BIG, BIG SWING IN ACTIVITY.
SAY THE DEAL IS SORT OF
HICCUPPING OR IT IS A BAD DEAL,
WOULD WE SEE THE SELL OFF
EXAGGERATED?
TED?
>>Guest: PARDON?
>>Neil: WOULD YOU SEE A BIG
SELL OFF IF THIS DOES NOT GO TO
WALL STREET'S LIKING OR WITH
FEWER PEOPLE ON WALL STREET THE
NEXT COUPLE OF WEEKS, IT COULD
BE EXAGGERATED.
>>Guest: I THINK WE SET UP.
THERE IS NO DISAPPOINTMENT IN
THIS MARKET.
IT IS A WING AND A PRAYER.
THE EXPECTATION IS THAT THERE
WILL BE A DEAL.
SUGAR PLUMB FAIRIES AND
CHRISTMASTIME, THE MARKET IS
SETTING ITSELF UP IF AN UGLY
RESPONSE IF THERE IS NO DEAL OR
AS YOU SUGGEST THE POSSIBILITY
YES, THERE IS A DEAL BUT IT
TURNS OUT TO BE A TROJAN HORSE
AND THAT IS A REAL POSSIBILITY.
I, LIKE A LOT OF FOLKS, I AM ON
THE SIDELINES WISH WE HAD MORE
MONEY BUT YOU NEED TO
WAIT-AND-SEE.
THE MARKET IS SCARY AT THE
MOMENT.
>>Neil: IN CHICAGO THEY ARE
SAYING WE WILL GET A DEAL, NO
WAY THEY COULD NOT.
WHAT IF WE DON'T HAVE A DEAL?
>>Guest: WELL, WE
SIGNIFICANTLY SAW THAT IN THE
MARKET TODAY WITH THE SELL OFF
IN GOLD.
NOT ONLY DID EQUITIES RALLY BUT
GOLD SOLD OFF $30.
I DISAGREE WITH TODD.
THIS IS NOT WALL STREET GIVING
INVESTORS AN EARLY CHRISTMAS
PRESENT, THIS IS WALL STREET
WITH NO PRESENT TO GIVE.
THE STOCK MARKET, THE S&P IS UP
15 PERCENT SO FAR THIS YEAR AND
AS WE HAVE SEEN INVESTORS, HEDGE
FUNDS, MONEY MARKET FUNDS, THEY
ARE MAJORLY UNDERINVESTED IN THE
STOCK MARKET.
THEY HAVE MISSED THE RALLY.
THEY HAVE BEEN EVERINVESTED IN
THE BOND MARKET.
THEY HAVE CATCHING UP TO DO WITH
JUST A FEW TRADING DAYS LEFT.
>>Neil: MAYBE WE ARE MAKING
TOO BIG OF A DEAL OF THE CLIFF
AND MAYBE WALL STREET IS NOT
OBSESSED.
>>Guest: IT IS TOPIC (A) AND
THE ONLY THING THAT CAN PUT THE
JOBS REPORT ON THE BACK BEENER.
HERE IS THE THING, SANDRA IS
RIGHT.
THIS IS THE BEST PLACE TO BE,
STOCKS.
BUT THERE ARE SO MANY HEADWINDS
WE ARE FACING NOT JUST THE NEXT
FEW WEEKS BUT IN 2013.
SO REGARDLESS OF A RESOLUTION OR
NOT, IF WE HAVE SOMETHING, WE
HAVE SOME SIGNIFICANT HEADWINDS
DID DEAL WITH AND THAT IS WHAT
MAKES THIS TREACHEROUS TERRITORY
GOING FORWARD, AT LEAST IN THE
IMMEDIATE FUTURE FOR STOCKS.
RIGHT NEW, IF THINGS ARE UP,
ENJOY IT WHILE IT LASTS.
>>Neil: YOU SAY THEY ARE
BUILDING A HOUSE OF RISKY CARDS.
>>Guest: I THINK I HAVE TO
DISAGREE WITH SANDRA, BUT
SANDRA, I THINK ANYONE THAT HAD
ANYTHING TO DO IN THIS MARKET
HAS DONE IT.
I THINK IT IS LATE FOR THE NEXT
SIX OR SEVEN TRADING DAYS TO DO
ANYTHING.
JANUARY COULD BE ANOTHER DEAL
DEPENDING ON HOW THIS CLIFF IS
RESOLVED IN A POSITIVE WAY BUT I
THINK MOST PEOPLE HAVE CLOSED
OUT THEIR YEAR.
I AM NOT SURE WHAT IS DRIVING
THE TRAIN.
OBVIOUSLY UP IS BETTER THAN
DOWN, PERHAPS IT IS ALL
ANTICIPATION.
>>Neil: TWO WEEKS TO
ANTICIPATE.
AND IT ALL ENDS.
WE SHALL SEE.
FOLKS, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
IN THE MEAN TIME, ADAM LANZA DID
A LOT OF PLANNING AHEAD HIS
RAMPAGE INCLUDING SMASHING TO
BITS SOMETHING THAT CAN HAVE
HELPED INVESTIGATORS CONNECT THE
PIECES.
WHAT HE DID THE DAY HE DIED THAT
MIGHT IS SLOWED DOWN THE
INVESTIGATION AS TO WHY SO MEN
DIED WITH HIM.
THE LEAD INVESTIGATOR ON THE
CASE IS NEXT.
I ALWAYS WAIT
UNTIL THE LAST MINUTE.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME R CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE RHYTHM OF LIFE.
[ whistle blowing ]
WHERE DO YOU HEAR THAT BEAT?
CAMPBELL'S HEALTHY REQUEST SOUP
LETS YOU HEAR IT...
IN YOUR HEART.
[ basketball bouncing ]
HEART HEALTHY.
GREAT TASTE.
MMM...
[ Male Announcer ] SOUNDS GOOD.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
>>Neil: IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, ADAM LANZA SMASHED
THE HARD DRIVE BEFORE GOING ON
THE RAMPAGE.
RICK?
Rick: WE HAVE A POSSIBLE
MOTIVE FOR THE SHOOTING REVEALED
BY OUR REPORTER ON OUR WEBSITE
REPORTING THAT ADAM MAY HAVE
SNAPPED BECAUSE HIS MOTHER WAS
PLANNING TO COMMIT HIM TO A
PSYCHIATRIC FACILITY.
THIS INFORMATION COMES FROM A
LIFELONG RESIDENT OF SANDY HOOK
WHOSE FATHER IS A PASTOR, SAYING
HE KNEW NANCY AND ADAM, ADAM WAS
JEALOUS OF THE TIME SHE
VOLUNTEERED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, SPENDING TIME
WITH KINDERGARTENERS AND SHE
ALREADY THE SCHOOL MORE THAN HIM
AND VICTIMS SHE SPENT TIME WITH
DURING THE LAST SCHOOL YEAR AND
SHE WAS PETITIONING THE COURT
FOR A STEP IN HAVING AN ADULT
COMMITTED TO A PSYCHIATRIC
FACILITY AND THIS SOURCE
KNEW ABOUT IT AND WAS VERY UPSET
IS ACCORDING TO LAW ENFORCEMENT
SOURCES HE WAS ANGRY AND THIS
COULD HAVE BEEN WHAT SET HIM OFF
AND IS PART OF THE POLICE
INVESTIGATION.
ALSO, TODAY, A VERY SAD DAY HERE
IN TOWN WHERE THERE WERE TWO
FUNERALS, BACK-TO-BACK FUNERALS
FOR TWO OF THE SIX-YEAR-OLD
VICTIMS OF THE SHOOTING, ONE
WOULD LOVED MATH AND RECESS, AND
LITTLE JESSICA REKOS WOULD LOVED
HORSES AND READING ABOUT THEM,
AND WRITING ABOUT THEM AND HOPED
TO GET ONE, A HORSE OF HER OWN
WHEN SHE WAS TEN.
HUNDREDS OF MOUNTERS ATTEMPTED
THE FUNERALS AND THE NEWTOWN
SCHOOL DISTRICT RE-OPENED SIX OF
THE SEVEN SCHOOLS OR FIVE OF THE
SEVEN SCHOOLS AND SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IS A CRIME
SCENE.
ANOTHER SCHOOL WAS THE SUBJECT
OF A BOMB THREAT OR UNSPECIFIED
THREAT AND MISS DID NOT OPEN
THAT ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE OTHER SCHOOLS IN TOWN
RE-OPENED.
THE SCHOOL BUSES HAD GREEN AND
WHITE RIBBONS.
A HIGH SCHOOL SENIOR DID NOT
EXPECT JOY IN-CLASS IT DID NOT
FEEL LIKE CHRISTMAS THIS YEAR.
>>Neil: YOU HEARD RICK THAT
MAYBE WHAT MATE HIM SNAP
INDICATIONS HIS MOTHER WOULD
WOULD HAVE HIM COMMITTED.
DO YOU KNOW ABOUT THIS,
LIEUTENANT?
>>Guest: THAT IS INFORMATION
THAT I DON'T KNOW THE SOURCE BUT
FRANKLY, IN OUR STAGE RIGHT NOW
OF INVESTIGATION, WE DON'T
RELEASE PIECES OF INFORMATION AS
THE INVESTIGATION PROGRESSES.
I HAVE IN INDEPENDENT KNOWLEDGE
OF THAT INFORMATION AS BEING
AUTHENTIC.
>>Neil: ON THIS SMASHED HARD
DRIVE, ADAM DESTROYED IT BEFORE
HE WENT ON THE RAMPAGE, BUT THAT
WAS A DELIBERATE ACT.
ARE YOU ABLE, OR YOUR MEN AND
WOMEN ABLE TO PUTTING IS LIKE
THIS TOGETHER?
>>Guest: I AGAIN HAVE TO THROW
A CORRECTION IF HERE.
WE HAVE GATHERED A GREAT DEAL OF
EVIDENCE FROM THE SECONDARY
CRIME SEEN WHICH IS A PRIVATE
RESIDENCE AND WE HAVE AMASS ADD
GREAT DEAL OF EVIDENCE WHERE SO
MANY LOST THEIR LIVES BUT WE
HAVE NOT ARTICULATED INFORMATION
ABOUT ANYTHING SEIZES OTHER THAN
THE WEAPONS THAT WERE INVOLVED
AND SEIZED IN THIS CASE.
EVERYTHING ELSE IS SIMPLY NOT
DISCUSSED.
>>Neil: LIEUTENANT AS WE SEE
ARE IF OF THE FUNERALS TAKE
PLACE, IT IS AMAZING TO ME THAT
THE COUNT AND THE FUNERAL COULD
HAVE BEEN SIGNIFICANTLY HIGHER
IF THE SHOOTER HAD NOT HEARD THE
SOUND OF SIRENS WHEN HE DID AND
HE TOOKLY LIFE.
IS IT YOUR SENSE THAT THE
WEAPONS HE DID HAVE, THAT HIS
INTENTION WAS TO TAKE MANY MORE?
>>Guest: CERTAINLY THE WEAPONS
IF HIS POSITION WAS VIOLENT,
EXTREMELY DEADLY.
THE MAXIMUM LOAD CLIPS HE HAD,
AND ADDITIONAL AMMUNITION,
SINGULARLY THE CARNAGE WAS
DEVASTATING AND TELL AND HEART
BREAKING BUT IT COULD HAVE BEEN
EXTREMELY WORST SITUATION IF THE
RESCUERS WERE NOT COMING.
>>Neil: I KNOW THIS COULD GO
BEYOND WHAT YOUR INVESTIGATION
IS INCLUDING AND YOU CANNOT TALK
ABOUT IT BUT THERE ARE SO MANY
SCHOOLS ACROSS THE COUNTRY, NOW,
THAT ARE BENEFITING UP THEIR OWN
SECURITY AND THEY HAVE BUZZ IN
SYSTEMS AND METAL DETECTORS AND
THE LIKE.
DO YOU THINK ANY OF THAT, AND
THIS SCHOOL HAD SUCH A SYSTEM,
CERTAINLY A BUZZING SYSTEM TO
MAKE SURE THAT PEOPLE COULD BE
IDENTIFIED BEFORE THEY COME IN,
BUT HE RAMPAGED THROUGH, DO YOU
THINK ANY OF THAT WOULD HAVE
DONE ANY GOOD IN THIS CASE OR
WAS ADAM INTENT ON DOING WHAT HE
DID AND NOTHING, NOTHING,
NOTHING WOULD STOP HIM?
>>Guest: WELL, CERTAINLY I
WISH I COULD ANSWER THAT
QUESTION.
THAT IS EXTREME DIFFICULT TO
ANSWER.
THIS YOUNG MAN WAS POUND --
BOUND AND DETERMINED TO GET IN
THE INSTITUTION.
HE FORCED HIS WAY, HE BROKE HIS
WAY INTO THAT SCHOOL AND I AM
NOT QUITE SURE THAT THERE IS
ANYTHING IN PLACE THAT WOULD
HAVE PREVENTED THAT FROM
OCCURRING.
>>Neil: LOOT -- LIEUTENANT I
KNOW YOU TALKED ABOUT THE GOAL
OF TALKING TO ADAM'S BROTHER AND
HIS FATHER, AND THAT HAS NOT
HAPPENED BUT THAT WAS THE GOAL.
HAVE YOU REACHED OUT TO EITHER?
>>Guest: I DON'T KNOW.
I DO KNOW WE WILL TALK TO ALL
FAMILY MEMBERS RELATED TO LANZA
AND WE CERTAINLY WILL INTERVIEW
ALL WITNESSES THAT CAN SHED ANY
LIGHT ON THIS INVESTIGATION.
CERTAINLY OUR GOAL IS TO ANSWER
EVERY QUESTION AS TO HOW AND WHY
THIS HEARTBREAKING TRAGEDY
OCCURRED.
>>Neil: THANK YOU, LIEUTENANT,
VERY MUCH.
WE CANNOT BLAME GOD FOR THE
TRAGEDIES A PRIEST AND RABBI
SAY, BUT SOMETIMES WE NEED TO
LOOK NO FURTHER THAN THE MIRROR.
>>Neil: TWO MORE YOUNG VICTIMS
WERE LAID TO REST AND SO MANY
QUESTIONS UP ANSWERED TODAY.
HOW CAN WE FIND PEACE AND KEEP
OUR FAITH AT A TIME LIKE THIS?
WE ASK A RABBI AND PASTOR, THANK
YOU BOTH FOR JOINING US.
RABBI, FIRST, A LAST FOLKS
QUESTION EVEN THE PRESENCE OF A
GOD WHEN SOMETHING LIKE THIS
HAPPENS.
>>Guest: IT WAS WRITTEN "A
BABY IS GOD'S OPINION THAT LIFE
SHOULD GO ON."
WHEN THIS HAPPENED, I THINK WE
ALL FELT, WHAT IS GOD'S OPINION
ABOUT 20 MURDERED BABIES?
THAT LIFE SHOULD NOT GO ON?
THAT IS WHERE FAITH BEGINS.
IT BEGINS AFTER WE HAVE BEEN
WOUNDED AND BROKEN.
IT DOESN'T BEGIN WITH SOME
ABSTRACT BELIEF.
IT BEGINS WHEN WE CLAW OUR WAY
BACK TO BELIEVING THAT THE GOOD
IN US WILL WIN.
THAT IS THE REWARD OF FAITH.
YOU MUST AT TIMES BELIEVE WHAT
YOU CAN'T SEE.
THAT PEOPLE ARE BETTER THAN THEY
SHOW.
THAT THERE IS HOPE.
THAT OUR CHILDREN WILL BE SAFE.
THE REWARD OF BELIEVING WHICH
YOU CAN'T ALWAYS SEE IS THAT
EVENTUALLY, YOU SEE WHAT YOU
BELIEVE.
>>Neil: FATHER, A LOT OF
PEOPLE LOOK AT WHAT HAPPENED IN
CONNECTICUT AND SAY, I KNOW THIS
IS ALL ABOUT FREE WILL AND GOD
GRANTS US THIS ABILITY, BUT HE
IS KNOWN FOR MIRACLES NOW AND
THEN.
WHY COULDN'T HE INTERVENE HERE?
>>Guest: WELL, IT IS NOT A
QUESTION OF WHETHER HE COULD
HAVE OR NOT.
IT IS A QUESTION OF, THE MYSTERY
OF EVIL THAT WE CONFRONT AND THE
BROKENNESS OF OUR WORLD.
AS A CHRISTIAN, WE BELIEVE THAT
LOVE IS MADE MANIFEST IN
BETHLEHEM.
WE CERTAINLY KNOW THAT HATRED
AND EVIL IS OFTEN MADE MANIFEST
IN CONNECTICUT.
BUT THE QUESTION, WHICH IS
STRONGER?
THE LIGHT STRONGER THAN
DARKNESS?
IS LOVE MORE POWERFUL THAN EVIL,
THAN HATE?
I BELIEVE IT IS.
I BELIEVE WHEN THAT BABY IS BORN
IN BETHLEHEM, WHAT HAPPENS IS
PEOPLE TAKE INTO HIMSELF ALL OF
HUMAN SUFFERING, THE SUFFERING
IN CONNECTICUT, THE SUFFERING IN
ALL OF HUMAN HISTORY, WHERE
EVERY MOTHER OR FATHER WHO HAS
WENT FOR A CHILD, EVERY TEAR
EVER SHED IN PUBLIC OR PRIVATE,
WILL ONE DAY BE OBLITERATED BY
THE POWER OF THAT LOVE.
I AGREE WITH THE RABBI, THAT THE
HOPE THAT WE HAVE IS, IT RESTS
IN OUR FAITH AND THE ABILITY TO
REACH BEYOND WHAT WE CAN SEE OR
FEEL AT THIS MOMENT.
THERE IS NO SENSE, WE CAN MAKE
NO SENSE OUT OF THIS BECAUSE
THIS IS SENSELESS.
EVIL IS SENSELESS, IT IS
UNREASONABLE.
IT IS ANTIREASON.
WHAT WE HAVE TO DO IS REACH FOR
THE LOVE THAT COMES TO US IN THE
MEMORY OF THESE CHILDREN, THE
LOVE OF THE NATION THAT IS
POURED OUT ON THAT SMALL TOWN
RIGHT NOW.
>>Neil: IT IS HUMAN NATURE, I
GUESS, AND RABBI I DIRECT THIS
TO YOU, FOR US TO WANT TO BLAME
SOMEONE, WE CAN BLAME VIOLENT
FILMS, VIDEO, GAMES, THE N.R.A.
IS UNDER ATTACK, PUTTING OUT A
STATEMENT SAYING WE ARE MADE UP
OF FOUR MILLION MOMS AND DADS,
WE ARE SADDENED AND HEART
BROKEN, BY THE NEWS OF THE
SENSELESS MURDERS.
OUT OF RESPECT FOR THE FAMILIES
WE HAVE GIVEN OUR TIME FOR MOURN
PRAYER AND A FULL INVESTIGATION
OF THE FACTS BEFORE COMMENTING.
WHAT DO YOU THING OF THAT?
>>Guest: WELL, IT IS A SADNESS
THAT IS DEEPLY REGRETTABLE THAT
THIS IS THEIR FIRST STATEMENT.
THEY HAVE BEEN SILENT SINCE THIS
HORRIBLE TRAGEDY.
WHAT I BELIEVE IS THAT PART OF A
DEEP FAITH IS HAVING PATIENCE
WITH THE QUESTIONS WE ASK.
WE DO LIVE IN A SOCIETY IN WHICH
WE ARE UNNATURALLY TRAINED TO
BELIEVE THAT THE COMMERCIAL WILL
BE OVER IN 30 SECONDS, THE MOVIE
IN TWO HOURS AND THE IN DEVELOP
WILL BE WRAPPING UP LOOSE ENDS.
LIFE IS NOT LIKE THAT.
THE SOLUTIONS TO THIS TRAGEDY
ARE NOT SIMPLE.
THEY TAKE US INTO PROFOUNDLY
COMPLEX SOCIAL ISSUES.
AS WELL AS ISSUES OF FREEDOM
THAT ARE NOT WIPED AWAY BY THIS
TRAGEDY.
WHAT I BELIEVE, WE MUST AVOID
PEOPLE WHO HAVE SIMPLE AND
IMMEDIATE ANSWERS TO THIS.
THIS CONVERSATION WE ARE ENGAGED
IN NOW WILL CERTAINLY RESULT, I
HELP IT WILL RESULT, IN MORE
SENSIBLE CRIMINAL OVER BOTH
AMMUNITION AND GUNS.
IT WILL RESULT, I HOPE, IN MORE
LOVING AND EXTENSIVE HELP FOR
THE MENTALLY ILL.
THAT WILL NOT END EVIL IN THE
WORD.
WHEN PEOPLE LIKE MY FRIEND BO
DIETL AND OTHERS SAY, LOOK, THE
ONLY WAY TO STOP A GUY WITH A
GUN IS WITH A GUN, WHEN THEY SAY
THAT, I BELIEVE THAT.
WHEN THE PEOPLE WHO ARE FOR GUN
CRIMINAL SAY, THERE ARE MORE
GUNS THAN PEOPLE IN THIS
COUNTRY, THAT HAS TO CHANGE AND
WHEN THE PRESIDENT SPOKE
ELOQUENTLY ABOUT THISES I
BELIEVE HIM, TOO, THESE ARE
SOCIAL ISSUES THAT CANNOT BE
PUSHED CORNERED OUR ABILITY TO
SEE THEIR IMPLICATIONS.
>>Neil: FATHERS FINALLY, WHEN
YOU TALK TO THE FLOCK, THEY ARE
GETTING INCREASINGLY SCARED
ABOUT THEIR FELLOW MAN.
THEY SEE THIS SHOOTING.
THEY SEE MALL SHOOTING A COUPLE
OF WEEKS PRIOR, AND THE SHOOT OF
IN AURORA AT A MOVIE THEATER.
THEY SEE INCREASINGLY HUMAN
BEINGS TURNING ON EACH OTHER IN
VIOLENT WAYS.
THESE COULD BE EXCEPTIONS TO THE
HUMAN RULE OF DECENCY BUT THEY
ARE MORE PUNCTUATED AND
INCREASINGLY MORE COMMON.
WHAT DO YOU TELL THEM?
>>Guest: I SAY THAT LOVE WINS
IN THE END.
IT COULD BE WE SEE A GREAT DEAL
OF EVIL BECAUSE OUR FOCUS IS
WHEN THE DOG BITES THE MAN, THAT
IS THE THING WE ARE ATTRACTED
TO, TO LOOKING AT, BUT IF WE CAN
FOCUS ON OTHER MODELS BECAUSE
THIS IS EVERY BIT AS MUCH GOOD
AND LOVE AND GENEROSITY IN THE
WORLD EVEN IN THE MIDDLE OF THE
TRAGEDY WE HAVE BEEN HEARING
STORIES OF TEACHER WHOSE HAVE
LOST THEIR LIVES PROTECTING THE
CHILDREN SO IF WE HELD UP THOSE
MODELS AND ENTER THE EXPENSE OF
GRIEF WITH THE PEOPLE, IT WILL
CALM OUR FEARS.
RIGHT NOW IS THE LEAST RATIONALE
MOMENT FOR DISCUSSING ANY DETAIL
OF POLICY.
IT IS THE EMBRACE LOVE.
>>Neil: I APPRECIATE YOUR
APPEARING.
WE WILL TRY TO PUT SOME
SEMBLENCE OF, WHY?
PASTOR RICK WARREN WILL BE HERE
TOMORROW.
>>Neil: DO YOU REMEMBER THE
AD, A FEW MONTHS AGO THAT MADE
FOOD STAMPS LOOK LIKE A BETTY
CROCKER COMMERCIAL.
>> IF YOU WANT TO EAT RIGHT,
SNAP CAN HELP, FOR PEOPLE WITH
LOW INCOME, YOUNG AND OLD.
>>Neil: THE GOVERNMENT HAS
DONE ONE BETTER COURTESY OF
YouTube.
OFFERING ON YouTube HOW TO
CUSTOMIZE GOVERNMENT BENEFITS TO
SUIT YOU.
PICK AND CHOOSE THE HAND OUTS
YOU HAVE COMING AND HAND OUT YOU
DID NOT KNOW EXISTED.
>> FIRST ANSWER ALL OF THE NINE
SIMPLE CORE QUESTIONS THAT ARE
ESSENTIAL TO NARROWING YOUR
RESULTS.
REMEMBER, THE MORE QUESTIONS YOU
ANSWER, THE PORE LIKELY YOU ARE
TO BE ELIGIBLE IF THE BENEFITS
THAT APPEAR ON YOUR RESULTS
LIST.
WE HOPE THIS HAS HELPED YOU ON
YOUR PATH TO GOVERNMENT BENEFITS
>>Neil: POINT AND CLICK TO THE
GIRL WHO FINDS WE ARE NOW
ENCOURAGING PEOPLE TO GET MORE
BENEFITS.
>>Guest: THIS SHOWS THE
HYPOCRISY OF PRESIDENT OBAMA AND
HIS ADMINISTRATION.
PRESIDENT OBAMA CLAIMS HE IS
NEGOTIATING THIS GOOD FAITH WITH
REPUBLICANS TO PREVENT THE
COUNTRY FROM DROPPING OFF THE
FISCAL CLIFF AND DEAL WITH OUR
ACUTE GOVERNMENT SPENDING
PROBLEM AND DOUBT.
WHAT DOES HE DO?
HE IS RECRUITING AMERICANS TO
GET MORE GOVERNMENT BENEFITS.
I TOOK THE TEST, AND I TOLD, I
ANSWERED 50 QUESTIONS, AND I LET
THE GOVERNMENT KNOW I AM FULLY
EMPLOYED, I OWN MY OWN HOME,
GUESS WHAT THE MAGIC NUMBER WAS
FOR ME?
I CAN QUALIFY IF EYE POPPING 28
GOVERNMENT PROGRAMS MOST OF
WHICH I HAVE NEVER HEARD OF.
THIS --.
>>Neil: AND YOU WORK AND HAVE
A JOB?
>>Guest: LAST TIME I LOOKED.
THIS IN ALL SERIOUSNESS --.
>>Neil: IN THIS CASE, WE
REACHED OUT, BY THE WAY, TO THE
SITE FOR A STATEMENT AND WE HAVE
NOT HEARD BACK, BUT HOPE SPRINGS
ETERNAL.
I UNDERSTAND THE METHOD, HERE IT
IS, HERE IS WHAT YOU ARE
ELIGIBLE FOR BUT YOU FOUND OUT
THAT AS A WORKING WOMAN YOU ARE
ELIGIBLE FOR A HECK OF A LOT AND
I CANNOT IMAGINE WHAT SOMEONE
WHO DOES NUT HAVE A JOB WHAT
THEY ARE ELIGIBLE FOR AND IT IS
GO GET IT.
>>Guest: THINK ABOUT THIS.
THE PRESIDENT SAID IN 2008 HE
WANTED TO TRANSFORM AMERICA.
YOU THINK ABOUT THE RHETORIC HE
IS SPEWING OUT WHERE HE WANTS TO
RAISE TAXES ON ONE CLASS OF
AMERICANS AND HE WANTS TO
ENCOURAGE MORE AMERICANS TO BE
DEPENDENT UPON GOVERNMENT, IT
LOOKS TO ME LIKE PRESIDENT OBAMA
WANTS TO TRANSFORM THIS COUNTRY
FROM A NATION OF EXCEPTIONALISM
AND INDIVIDUAL OPPORTUNITY INTO
WE ARE DEPENDENT ON GOVERNMENT
AND WE ASPIRE TO BE SLAVES OF
THE STATE.
>>Neil: YOU DON'T BUY THE
ARGUMENT THAT HAS BEEN OUT
THERE, THIS IS NOT THE PRESIDENT
OR THE WHITE HOUSE, BUT THIS HAS
BEEN COE LATED A BENEFITS
CHECKLIST, A MENU, YOU CAN CHECK
OFF, BECAUSE IT IS ALL OUT THERE
BUT IT HAS JUST NOW BEEN PUT
TOGETHER.
>>Guest: DON'T YOU FIND IT ODD
WE WANT AS A NATION TO HAVE A
PORTAL AND PUT ALL THE
TREMENDOUS AMOUNT OF GOVERNMENT
PROGRAMS INTO ONE PLACE SO MORE
PEOPLE COULD TAKE ADVANTAGE OF
THIS?
SHOULD WE BE TEACHING AMERICANS
INDIVIDUAL RESPONSIBILITY AND
HOW TO SELF SUSTAIN THEMSELVES?
I TOLD SOMEONE THE OTHER DAY
BEING ON WELFARE AND GOVERNMENT
PROGRAMS AIN'T GOING TO HELP YOU
BUY A HOUSE IN THE SUBURBS OR
SEND YOUR KIDS TO COLLEGE.
>>Neil: JUST WAIT.
JUST WAIT.
>>Guest: NOT YET.
>>Neil: AFTER THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING INCIDENT IN CONNECTICUT
, TAKE DOWN ANY AD,
MOVIE, SHOWING SHOOTING, PERIOD.
ARE WE OVERREACTING?
HI. I'M HENRY WINKLER.
AND I'M HERE TO TELL HOMEOWNERS
THAT ARE 62 AND OLDER
ABOUT A GREAT WAY
TO LIVE A BETTER RETIREMENT.
IT'S CALLED A REVERSE MORTGAGE.
[ Male Announcer ]
CALL RIGHT NOW
TO RECEIVE YOUR FREE
DVD AND BOOKLET
WITH NO
OBLIGATION.
IT ANSWERS QUESTIONS LIKE
HOW A REVERSE MORTGAGE WORKS,
HOW MUCH YOU QUALIFY FOR,
THE WAYS TO RECEIVE YOUR MONEY,
AND MORE.
PLUS, WHEN
YOU CALL NOW,
YOU'LL GET THIS MAGNIFIER
WITH L.E.D. LIGHT
ABSOLUTELY FREE.
WHEN YOU CALL THE EXPERTS
AT One Reverse Mortgage TODAY,
YOU'LL LEARN THE BENEFITS
OF A GOVERNMENT-INSURED
REVERSE MORTGAGE.
IT WILL ELIMINATE
YOUR MONTHLY MORTGAGE PAYMENTS
AND GIVE YOU TAX-FREE CASH
FROM THE EQUITY IN YOUR HOME.
AND HERE'S THE BEST PART --
YOU STILL OWN YOUR HOME.
TAKE CONTROL
OF YOUR RETIREMENT TODAY.
♪
>>Neil: AFTER THE SHOOTING,
THE EDITING FROM THE FLAT SCREEN
TO THE SILVER SCREEN, GUN SCENES
ARE HITTING THE CUTTING FLOOR.
>>Guest: MOVIE STUDIOS AND
DIVISION NETWORKS ARE MAKING
EFFORTS TO SHOW LESS VIOLENCE
FOR THE TIME BEING.
ONE COMPANY FOR EXAMPLE SCALED
BACK TODAY'S PREMIERE OF A
SLAVERY REVENGE FILM THAT WAS
SUPPOSED TO BE A BIG RED CARPET
MEDIA EVENT AND NOW IT WILL BE A
PRIVATE SCREENING FOR CAST, CREW
AND FRIENDS AND FAMILY AND
DELAYED THE WEEKEND PREMIERE OF
A NEW ACTION THRILLER, AND THE
FILM SOCIETY POSTPONED A
DISCUSSION WITH TOM CRUISE OUT
OF RESPECT FOR THE NEWTOWN
FAMILIES.
AND SCIENCE FICTION CHANNEL
RESCHEDULED VIOLENCE AT A HIGH
SCHOOL UNTIL NEXT WEEK AND
ANOTHER SPECIAL FROM DECEMBER 26
IS MOVED TO JANUARY 6, AND OUR
SISTER COMPANY, FOX SHOWS
REPEATS OF FAMILY GUY AND
AMERICAN DAD ON SUNDAY BECAUSE
OF POTENTIAL LICENSIVE CONTENT
IN THE NEW EPISODES SCHEDULED TO
ARAB AND SHOW TIME AIRS A
WARNING FOR VIEWERS BEFORE A
SHOW OF A SERIAL KILLER AND
HOMELAND, A SERIES OF TERRORISM
SAYING "IN LIGHT OF THE TRAGEDY
THAT HAS OCCURRED IN CONNECTICUT
THE FOLLOWING PROGRAM CONTAINS
IMAGES THAT COULD BE DISTURBING,
VIEWER DISCRETION IS ADVISED."
I WOULD NOT BET WE HAVE SEEN THE
LAST OF VIOLENCE ON THE SCREENS
BUT FOR NOW, IT SEEMS TO BE
HOLLYWOOD'S WAY OF PAYING
RESPECT.
>>Neil: SO, THANK YOU.
IS HOLLYWOOD GOING TOO FAR?
OR IS THERE A REAL PROBLEM WITH
THE ONSCREEN VIOLENCE?
WE ARE ASKING TO MOMS.
OVERREACTION?
>>Guest: NOTHING IS AN
OVERREACTION BUT THERE MAY NOT
BE A DIRECT CAUSAL RELATIONSHIP
BETWEEN VIOLENCE ON THE SCREEN
AND VIOLENCE COMMITTED BY PEOPLE
THAT ARE REALLY MENTALLY INSANE.
IT IS NOT AN EXCUSE.
BUT THIS MAN WAS TERRIBLY
STUBBED.
WHAT IS MORE OF A CAUSAL
RELATIONSHIP IS THE ISOLATION,
THE LACK OF ATTACHMENT, THE LACK
OF EMPATHY, THE FACT THIS CHILD
HAD NO SOCIAL RELATIONSHIPS.
THAT IS MORE OF A REASON KNOW
VIOLENCE AND THE MENTAL HEALTH,
CERTAINLY, OF THE YOUNG PEOPLE.
A LOT OF BOYS TODAY USE VIDEO
GAMES AND MOVIES LIKE THAT FOR
SOCIAL RELATIONSHIPS.
THEY SLIT AND -- SIT AND DO THEM
TOGETHER AND RUN OUTSIDE AND
PLAY FOOTBALL.
>>Neil: SO THERE IS NO
CONNECTION.
I UNDERSTAND WHY THE COMPANIES
WOULD IN THIS ENVIRONMENT COOL
IT ON THE ADS BUT A LOST THEM
ARE AFRAID NECESSITY WILL BE
FORCIBLY TOLD IF YOU ARE NOT
GOING TO TAKE THE GUNS AND
VIOLENCE OUT OF THE MOVIES CAN
YOU NOT PROMOTE THE MOVIES.
>>Guest: AS A PARENT, THE TWO
YOUNG BOYS AND AS A PARENTAL
EXPERT, THAT IS VERY IMPORTANT
AS A JOB FOR US AS PARENTS TO
SEE WHAT IS GOING ON IN THE
HOMES, TO MAKE SURE OUR CHILDREN
ARE NOT PLAYING VIOLENT VIDEO
GAMES AND THEY ARE NOT WATCHING
VIOLENT VIDEOS.
I HAVE A FIVE AND NINE-YEAR-OLD
AND IN MY HOME IT IT IS VERY
IMPORTANT WE ARE NOT WATCHING
THEM PLAYING VIOLENT VIDEO
GAMES.
I WOULD BE FOR, THEY WILL NOT GO
AWAY ENTIRELY BUT I WOULD MAKE
IT SO THAT WE COULD PROBABLY
TAKE IT AWAY, YES.
>>Neil: WE TEND TO OVERREACT
AND WHAT HAPPENS IS, THEN, WE GO
WAY OVERBOARD AND IF ALL WE KNOW
IN ADAM'S CASE WE HEARD A
REPORTER THIS HOUR SAYING WHAT
MIGHT HAVE SPURRED THIS RAGE WAS
THE MOTHER THINKING ABOUT
COMMITTING HIM, AND HE HEARD
ABOUT IT AND SHOT HER AND WENT
CRAZY AND SHOTS KIDS IN THE
CHOOSE ROOM WHERE SHE
VOLUNTEERED AND SUPPOSEDLY
ROBBING THEM OF THIS.
>>Guest: THAT IS ABSOLUTELY
TRUE.
I FEEL AS THOUGH THIS MAN WAS
VERY DISTURBED FOR VERY LONG
PERIOD OF TIME.
AND THE FACT THAT HE DIDN'T HAVE
THE PROPER HELP AND THE PROPER
MENTAL HEALTH, AND WASN'T IN AN
ENVIRONMENT WHERE HE COULD BE
SUPPORTED WAS THE PROBLEM.
THE --.
>>Neil: THEIR ARGUMENT IS WE
ARE DESENSITIZED AS ARE THE KIDS
BECAUSE IT IS ALL AROUND THEM
AND MAYBE IF IT IS NOT ALL
AROUND THEM WE WILL BE BETTER
789 >>Guest: IT WILL BE THERE,
REGARDLESS, THERE WILL ALWAYS BE
PROVIDE LENGTH VIDEO GAMES AND
VIOLENT MOVIES, IT IS A PARENTS'
CHOICE WHAT WE EXPOSE OUR
CHILDREN TO AND AT WHAT POINT.
>>Neil: IS THAT YOUR CALL OR
THE GOVERNMENT?
>>Guest: MY CALL.
>>Neil: DO YOU AGREE?
>> I BELIEVE THAT PARENTS NEED
TO KNOW THERE ARE OTHER THINGS A
CHILD CAN DO BESIDE VIDEO GAMES
AND THERE CAN BE A LIMIT ON THE
AMOUNT OF TIME.
IT IS NOT THE ONLY THING A CHILD
DOES.
CHILDREN NEED TO GO OUTSIDE.
GO OUT AND PLACE.
PARENTS NEED TO KNOW PARENTING.
PARENTS NEED TO KNOW THEY HAVE
TO RECOGNIZED WHEN THEIR CHILD
IS SO DISTURBED THEY GET THE
CHILD HELP RATHER THAN JUST
ISOLATE THE CHILD.
>>Guest: OR BE IN DENIAL.
>> OR USE THIS ENTERTAINMENT AS
A SUBSTITUTE.
>>Guest: I FEEL AS THOUGH BY
ISOLATING ADAM LANZA AND I AM
NOT THEIR PSYCHIATRIST AND THERE
IS NO JUDGMENT INTENDED, IT
BROUGHT HIM FURTHER INTO HIS OWN
MIND AND THAT IS WHAT MENTAL
ILLNESS IS, PEOPLE LIVE IF THEIR
OWN MIND.
>>Neil: THANK YOU BOTH,
LADIES.
SO MUCH WE DON'T KNOW.
TALK ABOUT VIDEOS THAT GO VIRAL
MY CONVERSATION WITH A
CONGRESSMAN THAT CONTINUES TO
GENERATE CONTROVERSY, FOCUS ON
REQUEST I WAS INTERRUPTING NOT
AT WHAT SHE WAS TRYING TO SAY
BUT WHY THAT CHIT CHAT PROVES WE
COULD ALL BE IN DEEP "CHIT."
..
>>Neil: EVERYTHING HE SAID WAS
TAXES, TAXES, TAXES, TAXES.
>> YOU NEVER STOPPED TALKING TO
LISTEN TO ME.
YOU HAVE NOT HEARD A I SAID.
>>Neil: WHAT WOULD YOU CUT?
>> THERE ARE A NUMBER OF THINGS
WE CAN LOOK AT.
>>Neil: YOU TOLD ME WHAT YOU
WOULD TO DO RAISE TAXES.
THAT IS WHAT YOU TOLD ME.
CREDITS.
>>Guest: YOU CANNOT TALK
ABOUT, YOU IS TO TALK ABOUT
REVENUE GENERATION.
>>Neil: I KNOW BUT IT IS 100
PERCENT OF WHAT YOU ARE TALKING
ABOUT.
>>Guest: IT AND NOT 100
PERCENT OF WHAT I AM TALKING
ABOUT.
IF YOU SHUT UP FOR A SECOND.
>>Neil: CONG ME
ONE ANYONE THAT YOU SAY YOU
WOULD CUT.
WHAT WOULD IT BE?
>>Guest: WELL I DO KNOW BUT I
HAVE TO HAVE TIME TO EXPLAIN IT.
>>Neil: YOU CANNOT TELL ME.
>>Guest: IT HAS TO BE SOME
TYPE DIALOGUE THE WE HAVE NOT
HAD THAT.
WE HAVE TO SEE WHAT IS BEING
PROPOSED SO WE CAN REACT TO IT.
WE HAVE SAID WHAT WE ARE WILLING
TO LOOK AT.
>>Neil: YOU HAVEN'T, HOPE
SPRINGS ETERNAL.
>> I KNOW WE DEBATED.
YOU DECIDED.
NO WONDER WE HAVE IN DEAL.
THAT WAS THE DEMOCRATIC TEXAS
CONGRESSWOMAN CONFIRMING WHY WE
ARE GOING TO MAKE A DEAL, WE ARE
GOING TO GO OVER THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
FROM SAID YOU BLUES FORKED, YOU
BULLIED, I SWITCHED THE EQUAL A.
AND ANOTHER, YOU ARE ARROGANT,
RUDE AND A BULLY.
ANOTHER, WHY DID YOU COME BACK
TO APOLOGIZE IF YOUR BEHAVIOR?
THE CONGRESSWOMAN WOULD NOT
ANSWER DIRECTOR QUESTIONS DID
NOT OFFER ONE PROGRAM TO CUT AND
TOLD YOU TO SHUT UP.
I WOULD HAVE HAD TOLD HER TO
STICK IT WHERE THE SUN DON'T
SHINE.
>> AND ANOTHER SAYS THE ONLY
THING YOU HAD TO APOLOGIZE FOR
WAS THE VEIN POPPING OUT OF YOUR
NECK.
I HAVE NOT SEEN YOU THIS ANGRY
SINCE THE HOSTESS BANKRUPTCY.
>> SHE WAS OVERTIME TOP, TALK
ABOUT A DIMWIT.
>> MY PROBLEM WITH THE
CONGRESSWOMAN, LIKE MANY OF HER
COLLEAGUES, WHEN IT COMES TO
SPELLING OUT HOW THEY WILL
CONTROL SPENDING THEY CAN'T AND
THEY WON'T.
I OFFERED EVERY OPPORTUNITY I
COULD TO STATE JUST ONE PROGRAM
SHE WOULD CUT.
JUST ONE.
NOTHING.
NOT ONE.
NOUN IS ADDRESSING THE SPENDING
PROGRAM.
FROM PALM BEEP, I WISH YOU CUT
HER OFF.
>> JOHN, SHE IS A POSTER CHILD
OF WHAT IS WRONG WITH CONGRESS.
>> AND ANOTHER FROM MEN
MICHIGAN, YOU ARE MY SUPER HERO
THE ONLY ONE WHO INSISTS THE
QUESTIONS BE ASKED AND ANSWERED.
>> AND ANOTHER, PLEASE STOP
BEING SO RUDE, YOU MAKE ME
ASHAMED TO CALL MYSELF A
CONSERVATIVE.
>> YOU MAKE ME ASHAMED TO THINK
AS A CONSERVATIVE YOU WOULD
ACCEPT THE CONGRESSWOMAN'S
CONSTANT DODGING.
>> AND ANOTHER, FROM TED, YOU
DESERVE A RAISE.
SHE WAS MORE DIFFICULT THAN THE
I-MAN.
>> NO ONE IS AS DIFFICULT AS 9
-- I-MAN.
>> SHE IS AN IDIOT FOR
BLATHERING BUT YOU ARE A BIGGER
IT IDEA FOR INVITING HER.
>> AND RIGHT AFTER THAT EXCHANGE
I HAD A DOUBLE SHOT OF SCOTCH
AND YOU LOOK BETTER BLURRED.
EVERYTHING DOES.
>> I CAN WELL UNDERSTAND YOU
REACHING FOR THE BOLT BUT
SOMETIMES WITH GUESTS LIKE THAT,
SO DO I.
NOT DURING THE SHOW.
THE PROBLEM IS, WE HAVE
POLITICIANS WHO ARE DRUNK ON
SPENDING AND I AM SAYING,
PERHAPS RUDELY, IS THAT THEY
HAVE TO SOBER UP OTHERWISE THE
COUNTRY IS GOING DOWN.
THAT DOESN'T NOON I AM SAYING WE
SHOULD NOT SEE TAXES AT PART OF
THE DEAL.
AS I HAVE SAID MANY TIMES
ELECTIONS DO HAVE CONSEQUENCES,
AND ONE OF THE CONSEQUENCES OF
THIS ELECTION IS THAT VOTERS
CLEARLY FAVORED THE RICH PAYING
MORE TAXES.
I AM NOT FOR THAT.
WE WILL LIKELY SEE NOTHING FROM
THAT.
BUT, LET'S MOVE ON AND ACCEPT
THAT SO WE CAN DO WHICH: CUT
SPENDING.
IT MUST BE PART OF AN OVERALL
DEAL ADDRESSING THE PROPENSITY
TO SPEND MORE THAN WE TAKE IN.
THE CONGRESSWOMAN ISN'T THE
PROBLEM.
HER INSISTENCE THAT SPENDING
ISN'T EVEN AN ISSUE, THAT IS THE
PROBLEM.
I MIGHT STRIKE SOME OF YOU AS
WEIRD AND RUDE, AND A LITTLE IN
YOUR FACE BUT WE DON'T HAVE TIME
FOR BLUSTER OR NONANSWERS.
IF YOU ARE LOOK AT RACES --
RAISING QUESTIONS, WE HAVE TO
ADDRESS SPENDING.
WE ARE LOOKING AT 50 DEAL, AND A
YEAR AGO THEY WERE TALKING $3 IN
SPEND CUTS FOR $1 IN TAX HIKES.
AND GOD KNOWS NOW WHERE IT WILL
END.
THIS IS SOMETHING THE NEXT
TREASURY SECRETARY WILL HAVE TO
TAKE UP.
WE UNDERSTAND AMERICAN EXPRESS
C.E.O. HAS BEEN MENTIONED MORE
PROMINENTLY AS A POSSIBILITY
SUCCESSOR.
WE ARE WATCHING WITH MORE OF
THIS TONIGHT.
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.