>> MY DAUGHTER EMILY.
SHE IS STAND GIVING LOVE AND
STIPULATE TO ALL OF THOSE
VICTIMS BECAUSE THAT IS IS THE
TYPE OF PERSON SHE S. NOT
BECAUSE OF PARENTING MY WIFE
AND I COULD HAVE DONE, BUT
BECAUSE THOSE WERE GIFTS GIVEN
TO HER BY HER HEAVENLY FATHER.
>> A VERY POWERFUL EXPRESSION
FROM ROBBY PARKER.
HE'S THE FATHER OF SIX YEAR
OLD EMLY PARKER, ONE OF THE
VICTIMS IN THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
FEW TOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> HELLO, I AM MIKE HUCKABEE.
I AM COMING TO YOU LIVE IN NEW
YORK CITY .
OUR NATION IS IN SHOCK OVER
THE SENSELESS AND UNSPEAKABLE
TRAGEDY THAT TOOK PLACE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THE SHOOTER KILLED HIS MOTHER
IN HER HOME AND THEN TO A
ELEMENTARY COOL WHERE HE GUND
DOWN 20 OPPORTUNITIS AND TEACH
ARES BEFORE HE TOOK HIS OWN
LIFE .
MOLLY?
NTHE COMMUNITY HAS BEEN
PULLING TOGETHER SINCE THIS
HORRIFIC MASSACRE.
THERE ARE NUMEROUS VIGILS AND
WE ARE GETTING WORD THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS IT JOINING
THE COMMUNITY AND AN
INTERFAITH VIGIL.
THER JOINING TOGETHER AND
HEALING THE COMMUNITY.
IT IS IT A DIFFICULT AND LONG
ROAD AHEAD WHEN YOU THINK
ABOUT THE VICTIMS IN THIS
CASE.
AND SO MANY LIVES LOST AND 12
LITTLE GIRLS AND EIGHT LITTLE
BOYS AND SIX WOMEN.
TWO OF THE WOMEN KILLED WERE
SO YOUNG.
BEGINNING THEIR CAREERS IN
EDUCATION .
IN THEIR TWENS AND ONE JUST 30
YEARS OLD AND ALL OF THESE
WOMEN TRYING TO PROTECT THE
CHILDREN.
THE YOUNGEST VICTIM NAMED
NOAH.
YOU LOOK AT THE LIST OF THE
CHILDREN'S NAMES AND THE NAMES
YOU HEAR IN CLASSROOMS ALL
OVER AMERICA.
CHARLOTTE, AND ANNA, AND
DANIEL.
TINY LITTLE PEOPLE CUT DOWN
BEFORE THEY SO MUCH MUCH LIFE.
THAT'S WHAT PRESIDENT OBAMA
TALK BODY THE LIVES THAT WERE
CUT SHORT.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER TALKING
ABOUT THE TRAGEDY AND GIVING A
PICTURE OF WHAT HAPPENED IN
THE SCHOOL.
NOT UNEXPECTED DETAILS.
WE KNEW THEY WERE GOING TO BE
HORRIBLE BUT THE EXTENT OF THE
DETAIL WAS CLINICAL.
NEARLY ALL OF THE VICTIMS HAD
MULTIPLE GUN HOT.
THREE-LEN GUN SHOT WOUNDS AND
THOSE ARE THE FOLKS HE HAD A
CHANCE TO EXAMINE HIMSELF.
HE PARTICIPATED IN 7 OF THE
EXAMS PERSONALLY.
THE PAPERWORK IS COMPLETED AND
NOW, IT IS TIME FOR THE
FAMILIES TO HAVE A CHANCE TO
SEE THEIR LOVED ONES AND
EXPERIENCE THE GREAT LOSS AND
IN THE COMING DAYS, FUNERALS
AND MEMORIAL SERVICES AND A
VERY LONG ROAD TO RECOVERY FOR
THE COMMUNITY.
GOVERNOR.
>> MOLLY, THANK YOU FOR YOUR
REPORT THERE IN NEWTOWN.
>> MAYBE IT IS SIMPLEP THE
ATTEMPT TO EXPRESS OUR
COLLECTIVE SHOCK WHEN WE SAY
WE ARE TRYING TO MAKE SENSE OF
THE HORRIFIC SHOOTING IN THE
SANDY HOOKS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
IT IS IT NOT SENSE TO A
RATIONAL HUMAN BEING.
THE GOVERNOR MALLOY GOT IT
RIGHT WHEN HE SAID ERIL
VISITED THE COMMUNITY.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SPOKE MORE AS
A PARENT THAN A POLITICIAN AND
QUOTED THE BIBLE TO BRING
COMFORT TO THE NATION.
CHURCHES WERE FILLED IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT LAST
NIGHT AS CANDLELIGHT VIGILS
WERE HELD TO GRIEVE FOR THE 27
INNOCENT PEOPLE KILLED AND
THOSE SHATTERED BY THE CRAZED
CARNAGE.
ON FRIDAY, NEAL CAVUTED ME,
WHERE WAS GOD IN WE HAVE
SYSTEMATICALLY REMOVED GOD
FROM OUR SCHOOLS AND PUBLIC
ACCOUNT ACTIVITIES AND AT THE
MOMENT OF THE CALAMITY WE
WONDER WHERE IT WAS.
THE LIBERAL WAVE HAD A VIOLENT
AND JUMPED TO THE CONCLUSION
THAT IF I SAID PRAYER WAS IN
SCHOOL THE SHOOTING WOULD NOT
HAVE HAPPEN.
I SAID NOTHING OF THE SORT.
IT IS FAR MORE THAN PRAYER AND
BIBLE READING.
IT IS IT THE FACT THAT PEOPLE
SUE A CITY SO WE HAVE NO MAJOR
16 OR CHRISTMAS CAROL CHURCHES
AND CHRISTIAN OWNED BUSINESSES
ARE TOLD TO SURRENDER THE
VALUES UNDER THE EDICT OF THE
GOVERNMENT ORDERS TO PROVIDE
TAX-FUNDED ABORTION PILLS .
WE SAY THINGS ARE SINFUL AND
SAY THEY ARE DISORDERS AND
SOMETIMES WE SAY THEY ARE
NORMAL AND HAVE TO ABANDON BED
ROCK MEMIORAL TRUTHS, WE WERE,
WHERE WAS GOD?
WHY ESCORTED HIM OUT OF OUR
CULTURE AND MARCHED HIM OUT OF
THE PUBLIC SQUARE AND THEN
SURPRISED THAT A CULTURE
REFLECTS WHAT IT IS IT BECOME.
AS SOON AS THE TRAGEDY
UNFOLDED HE SHOWED UP.
IN THE LIVES OF TEACHERS WHO
PUT THEIR LIVES BETWEEN THE
GUNMEN AND THE STUDENTS AND IN
POLICEMEN WHO RUSH SCHOOL NOT
KNOWING IF THEY WOULD BE MET
WITH A BARAGE OF STUDENTS.
AND HUGS AND TIERCE OF PARENTS
AND TEACHERS THAT LIVED
THROUGH THE SLAUGHTER AND
OVERFLOWED CHURCH SERVICES
WHERE PEOPLE LIT CANDLES AND
PRAYED HE SHOWED UP IN THE
WHITE HOUSE WHERE THE
PRESIDENT ENVOKED HIS NAME AND
QUOTED FROM HIS BOOK THEN IN A
FEW DAYS, WE'LL GOD TO EXCUSE
HIMSELF.
AND ANNOUNCE IN OUR ARROGANT
PRIDE THAT WE HAVE EVOLVED
BEYOND NEEDING HIM AND SOMEONE
WILL SUGGEST WE HAVE A LAW TO
STOP THIS.
WE DON'T HAVE TO PASS A NEW
ONE.
THERE IS ONE THAT WORKS IF WE
TEACH AND OBSERVE IT.
SHAW SHALT NOT KILL.
THERE ARE NINE OTHERS.
BUT TO TELL THEM ABOUT THAT
WOULD REQUIRE BRINGING GOD
BACK AND WE KNOW HOW
UNACCEPTABLE THAT MIGHT BE.
GERALDO RIVARY IS STANDING BY
IN NEWTOWN, BUT MORE
IMPORTANTLY GERALDO, I CAN'T
THINK OF ANY MAJOR AMERICAN
TRANNEL DEE THAT YOU HAVE NOT
SEEN UP CLOSE AND PERSONAL IN
THE LAST 40 YEARS.
HOW DOES THIS ONE COMPARE TO
THE TRAGIC EVENTS THAT YOU
COVER AS A REPORTER IN THE
PAST FOUR DECADES.
>> GOVERNOR, LET ME IF I MAY,
START BY YOU KNOW, GIVING YOU
A ELECTRONICALLY A BIG EMBRACE
AND AGREEING WITH YOU.
THIS CRIME, THIS CRIME, THIS
ATROCITY WAS A GODLESS ACT AND
THAT THIS PERPETRATOR WAS IN
EVERY WAY THE DEVIL INCARNATE
HERE ON EARTH.
HE WAS THE AGENT OF THE
APOCALYPSE.
IP AM NOT A PREACHER, I HAVE
AN UNUSUAL AS YOU KNOW
THELOGICAL BACKGROUND, MY
JEWISH MOTHER AND CATHOLIC
FATHER.
BUT IT IS IMPOSSIBLE FOR ME TO
MISS THE POINT THAT WERE THIS
A FAITH-BASED YOUNG MAN, HE
COULD NOT POSSIBLY HAVE
PERPETRATED THE EVIL.
THIS WAS NOT JUST CRIME.
THIS WAS EVIL.
THIS WAS DEBASE.
THIS WAS SOMETHING THAT SO
UTTERLY BEYOND THE REALM OF
APPROPRIATE CIVILIZED CONDUCT.
THIS WAS SOMEONE WHO WANTED TO
INFLICT PAIN AND IN INFLICTING
PAIN, HE CHOSE THE MOST
VULNERABLE VICTIMS, SIX YEARS
OLD AND 7 YEARS OLD IN FIRST
GRADE AND TOOK THAT BIG GUN
AND POSING AS IF HE WAS A
NINJA CAR WAR GARBED IN BLACK
AND STUCK IT TO THE TERRIFIED
CHILDREN AND ENDED THEIR LIVES
AND SHOT THEM AGAIN AND AGAIN
AND AGAIN.
THIS IS IT, GOVERNOR, THAT NO
CORRESPONDANT HAS SEEN THIS
KIND OF CARNAGE HERE IN NEW
ENGLAND, IN A BEAUTIFUL 300
YEAR OLD COMMUNITY TO WHICH
PEOPLE FLOCK WOULD FOR ITS
SAFETY AND ITS SECURITY AND
TRADITIONS AND CHURCHES, AND
ITS SURRENITY.
HE PERPETRATED AN OBSCENITY.
IF THIS IS NOT THE DEVIL AT
WORK, I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT IS,
GOCH GOCH.
>> I CAN'T IMAGINE THE GRIEF
AND PAIN THAT YOU HAVE SEEN
THERE.
AS YOU HAVE BEEN THERE, PEOPLE
APPRECIATE THE MEDIA BRINGING
ATTENTION TO THE PLIGHT AND
THEN THERE COMES A TIME WHEN
THEY WANT PEOPLE TO LEAVE AND
THEY NEED PEACE.
ARE THEY THEY AT THAT POINT OR
DO THEY APPRECIATE THE
ATTENTION THAT IS IT FOC OUSED
ON NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> I HAVE TO WORRY THAT THIS
WAY.
I GOT HERE LATE INTENTIONALLY
I HAVE BEEN AN OBSERVER MUCH
MORE AN OBSERVER THAN A
REPORTER.
I FELT AN ABSOLUTE QUEASINESS
ABOUT GOING UP TO PEOPLE
ANDING THEM.
WE USED INTERMEDIARIES TO SEE
IF THEY SHARED THE STORE
STORSES.
CRIG MY BROTHER WAS HERE ALL
DAY YESTERDAY AND SOME
RESPONDED WITH BITTERNESS AT
THE INTRUSION.
AND OTHERS ARE THANKFUL FOR
THE COMPASSION AND THE
SUPPORT.
I AM SURE THAT THE HEALER IN
CHIEF, AND THE PRESIDENT GETS
HERE TOMORROW NIGHT, HE WILL
BE ABLE TO LET EVERYONE IN THE
COUNT, WHO SAID THEY DON'T
KNOW AND MOST OF THEM DO, THAT
THE WORLD ASK NATION IS UNITE
THAT WE ARE ALL PARENTS OF
THESE CHILDREN AND TONIGHT, AS
PEOPLE WATCH, AND HUG THEIR
CHILDREN, THAT'S THE BEST WAY
WE CAN FIGHT BACK AGAINST THIS
OBSCENE DEAL AND MINI
HOLOCAUST.
I NEVER USE THE EXPRESSION
HOLOCAUST IT CONNOTES THE MOST
DREADFUL THING THAT HAPPENS IN
THE HUMAN SUSPICIOUS.
THAT WAS FOR THE 20 CHILDREN
THE HOLOCAUST AND THAT EVIL
THAT THIS MAN PERPETRATED
AGAINST THEM WAS AS MUCH LIKE
THE EVIL THE NAZIES
PERPETRATED AS KIDNAPPING I
CAN THINK MUCH.
>> GERALDO, THANK YOU FOR
JOINING US IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
YOU WILL HAVE A LIVE SHOW
LATER THIS EVENING FROM
NEWTOWN.
AND WE KNOW FOLKS WILL WANT TO
WATCH THAT AT 10 O'CLOCK
EASTERN TIME.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
WILEHEAR FROM A MOTHER WHOSE
SON WAS AT SANDY HOOK AND HE
WAS IN THE SCHOOL DURING THE
SHOOTING YESTERDAY.
THAT'S NEXT
initiated.
Neural speeds
increasing to 4G LTE.
Brain upgrading to a quad-core
processor.
Predictive intelligence
with Google Now complete.
Introducing DROID DNA by HTC.
It's not an upgrade
to your phone.
It's an upgrade to yourself.
>> AS PARENTS OF THE STUNES IN
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
GOT THE WORD OF THE SHOOTING,
THEY RUSHED TO THE SCHOOL AND
NEARBY FIRE HOUSE AND FEARING
THE WORST AND HOPING AND
PRAYING FOR THE BEST.
THAT'S WHERE CHRIS TEEN
WILFRED FOUND HER SENYEAR OLD
SON SAFE AND SOUND AND SHE
JOINS US ON THE PHONE, CHRIS
TEEN, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
IT IS IT A DIFFICULT TIME FOR
YOU AND I APPRECIATE YOU BEING
WILLING TO VISIT WITH US ABOUT
IT >> WHEN YOU FIRST HEARD
SOMETHING HAPPENED IN THE
SCHOOL, WHERE WERE YOU AND
WHAT DID YOU HEAR AND WHAT DID
YOU DO?
>> I WAS AT HOME SITTING AT MY
KITCHEN TABLE WITH MY HUSBAND.
HE DECIDE TOD WORK FROM HOME
YESTERDAY.
A NEIGHBOR HAD COME OVER TO
PICK UP A CHRISTMAS PRESENT I
HAD AT MY HOUSE FOR HER SON.
AND WE RECEIVED AN AUTOMATED
PHONE CALL THAT THE SCHOOLS
WERE IN LOCK DOWN DUE TO A
REPORTED SHOOTING.
SHE GOT ON THE PHONE TO HER
HUSBAND AND HE SAID HE THOUGHT
IT WAS SANDY HOOK WE PULLED UP
ON THE COMPUTER THAT IT WAS
SANDY HOOK.
AND SHE LEFT TO GO TO HER
HUSBAND, AND WE LOADED OUR TWO
YEAR OLD IN THE CAR AND HEADED
TO SCHOOL .
>> YOU HAD NO IDEA ON YOUR WAY
TO SANDY HOOK WHERE YOUR SON
WAS OKAY OR NOT, DO YOU?
>> NO, NO.
WE HAD NO IDEA.
ALL WE COULD DO IS HOPE AND
PRAY.
THAT HE WAS OKAY.
HOW DUFIRST FIND OUT THAT YOUR
SON WAS OKAY?
>> WE PUMED UP ALONG WITH
MANY, MANY OTHER PARENTS ALL
ARRIVING AND CONVERGING ON THE
MAIN ROAD AND START TOTTED RUN
DOWN THE DIRT ROD THAT WE
FOUND TO THE SCHOOL, THE
LITTLE SIDE ROAD.
AND WE WERE IMMEDIATELY
DIRECTED BY THE POLICE THAT
OH, CHILDREN WERE EVACUATED TO
THE FIRE HOUSE.
AND JUST RAN IN THERE AND
STARTED TO FRANTICALLY LOOK AS
EVERYBODY WAS PACKED IN THERE.
KNOW, SPOTTED HIS TEACH
ARE FIRST.
HE'S OKAY HE'S RIGHT HERE AND
GOT HIM OFF OF THE GROUND AND
GAY HIM TO ME.
>> OH, I CAN'T IMAGINE CHRIS
TEEN AS A PARENT.
IP JUST CAN'T GET MY ARMS
AROUND THE EMOTION THAT YOU
MUST HAVE HAD WHEN YOU SAW
YOUR SON WAS OKAY.
I AM ASSUMING YOU GRABBED HIM
AND HUGGED HIM ALMOST TO THE
POINT OF SQUEEZING THE AIR OUT
OF HIM.
HE IS LIKE I AM OKAY.
I DONE CRY.
I WAS BRAVE.
AND YOU KNOW, I AM OKAY.
AND I SAID OKAY.
AND PASSED HIM TO MY HUSBAND
SO HE COULD HUG HIM AND THEN
MY THOUGHTS WENT TO ONE OF MY
BEST FRIEND'S DAUGHTERS WHO I
KNEW WAS AT WORK AND I
IMMEDIATELY STARTED TO LOOK
FOR HER AND FOUND HER AND TOOK
HER.
AND TOLD HER MANAGER ON THE
PHONE WITH HER MOTHER.
NTHAT MUST HAVE BEEN ONE HAPPY
CONVERSATION.
HAD THAT MOTHER KNOWN ABOUT
THE PHONE CALL.
YES, HAD KNOWN.
SHE HAD KNOWN.
SHE HAD CALL WOULD WHILE WE
WERE ON THE WAY TO THE SCHOOL.
HOW DO YOU IXPLAIN TO YOUR SON
WHAT HAPPENED.
THAT IS A HORRIBLE THING TO
EXPLAIN SOMETHING SO HEINOUS
AND EVIL TO A CHILD IN A WAY
THAT MAYBE HE COULD UNDERSTAND
IT.
>> WE JUST TOLD HIM THAT, THAT
VERY BAD MAN CAME IN THE
SCHOOL AND HURT A LOT OF
PEOPLE.
AND YOU KNOW, HE WAS EXPLAINED
AND WE FOUND OUT NAMES OF
PEOPLE THAT HE WAS FRIENDS
WITH AND KNEW, WE LET HIM
KNOW.
AND YOU KNOW.
KEEP CHECKING IN WITH HIM.
I HIM ONCE AN HOUR HOW HE IS
DOING AND IF HE IS OKAY.
AND JUST TELL HIM IF HEMENT TO
TALK WE ARE HERE.
>> CHRIS TEEN, THERE IS NOT A
PARENT IN AMERICA THAT IS NOT
RIVETED BY WHAT YOU HAVE BEEN
THROUGH.
I AM SOY GLAD YOU AND YOUR SON
ARE OKAY AND ALL OF YOUR
FAMILY.
I KNOW IT IS A HARD TIME AND
YOU HAVE KNOWN TEACHERS AND
OTHER KIDS WHO ARE NOT OKAY.
I APPRECIATE YOU LETTING US
INVADE YOUR PRIVACY AND
THARCHING YOU FOR LETTING US
UNDERSTAND WHAT YOU WENT
THROUGH.
NTHANK YOU.
>> THAT WAS CHRIS TEEN
WILFORD.
HER SON 7 YEAR OLD WAS SAFE.
WHAT A HORRIBLE EXPERIENCE.
AND WHAT ARE DETECTIVES DOING
NOW TO PIECE TOGETHER WHY THE
SHOOTING HAPPENED?
WEELERWILL HELP ANSWER THAT.
[ HEART BEATING,
MONITOR BEEPING ]
Woman: WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
HOMEOWNERS INSURANCE
DOESN'T COVER FLOODS?
[ HEART RATE INCREASES ]
Man: A FEW INCHES OF WATER
CAUSED ALL THIS?
[ HEART RATE INCREASES ]
Woman #2: BUT I DON'T EVEN LIVE
NEAR THE WATER.
WHAT YOU DON'T KNOW ABOUT FLOOD
INSURANCE MAY SHOCK YOU --
INCLUDING THE FACT
THAT A PREFERRED RISK POLICY
STARTS AS LOW AS $129 A YEAR.
FOR AN AGENT, CALL THE NUMBER
THAT APPEARS ON YOUR SCREEN.
Every human being
is unique.
And there is one store
that recognizes it.
The Sleep Nuer Store.
The only place in the
world you'll find the
extraordinarily comfortable
Sleep Number Experience.
An exclusive collection of
innovations that totally
individualize your sleep.
Perfectly comfortable
pillows that adjust to
your size and shape.
Temperature-balancing
bedding.
Dual warmth comforters.
All designed around the
Sleep Number Bed: A bed
with dual-air technology
that allows you to adjust
to the support your
body needs.
Each of your bodies.
In the name of human
individuality: The Sleep
Number Collection.
Discover how our sleep
professionals can
individualize your sleep
experience.
Exclusively at one of our 400
Sleep Number Stores nationwide.
Sleep Number.
Comfort Individualized.
This holiday season, give
the gift that's magical:
the innovative AirFit
adjustable pillow at
special 30% savings.
>> IT WAS UNREAL AND I CAN'T
BELIEVE IT THAT IT IS IT TRUE.
I CAN'T FATHOM THIS.
NOTHING MAKES SENSE LIKE THIS.
THIS IS IT SENSELESS.
>> STILL NO MOTIVE KNOWN AS TO
WHY THE SHOOTER DID WHAT HE
DID BEFORE TAKING HIS OWN
LIFE.
WHAT CLUES ARE PEOPLE LOOKING
FOR.
JOHN IS A POLICE DETECTIVE.
JOHN, BEFORE I GET IN THE
EVIDENCE GATHERING WHICH I
KNOW THE POLICE ARE THROUGH
NOW.
I DON'T THINK MOST PEOPLE
UNDERSTAND.
WHEN THE POLICE OFFICERS FIRST
AROUND ON THE SCREEN LIKE THEY
DID IN SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
THEY HAD NO IDEA WHAT THEY MAY
FACE.
THEY MAY FACE ONE GUN OR FIVE
GUNS OR EXPLOSIVES.
THEY RUN IN UATION WHERE THEY
MAY HAVE TO MAKE A SPLIT
SECOND DECISION WHERE THEY MAY
ACT THE LIVES OF KIDS.
>> IT IS TRUE.
YOU NIVER CAN FULLY PREPARE
BECAUSE YOU NEVER KNOW WHAT
THE SCENARIO IS.
WE HAVE EMERGENCY ACTION PLANS
FOR THESE SHOOTERS.
AND THIS IS WHAT THE SITUATION
WAS.
AND WE HAVE POLICE OFFICERS
AND DETECTIVES AND UNITS THAT
TRAIN FOR THIS ALL OF THE TIME
FOR THIS TYPE OF SCENARIO.
AND SO WHEN THEY TURN OUT.
THEY ESTABLISH A PERIMETER AND
SET UP A MOBILE COMMAND BASE
AND PLOY THE TROOPS AND VET
INFORMATION AS IT COMES IN.
AND THEY WILL USUALLY WORK IN
A MINIMUM OF FOUR TEEMS THAT
GO THROUGH THE DOOR AND DO A
GRID SEARCH.
AND MAYBE THEY WILL ACCESS TO
POIGNS OF THE BUILDING AND
BEING AWARE OF THE CROSS FIRE
SCENARIO TO STAY AWAY FROM
THAT.
THEY GO IN AND THEY DON'T KNOW
IF THE DOORS ARE BOOBY TRAPPED
OR IF THERE IS MORE THAN ONE
SHOOTER.
AND THOSE PEOPLE MAY NOT HAVE
ALL OF THE INFORMATION.
AFTER COLUMBINE.
ONE OF THE CHANGES IN DEALING
WITH LAW ENFORCEMENTS, AS IN
COLUMBINE THEY WAITED A MINUTE
TO ASSESS WHAT WAS GOING O.
AND THE PROTOCALL IS YOU GO IN
AND TRY TO GET TO THE SHOOTER
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
AND THAT MEEPS THE FIRST GUYS
IN THERE ARE PUTTING THEIR IN
HARM'S WAYS.
A CRIME LIKE THIS IS USUAL LIE
DONE WITHIN FIVE MINUTES.
YOU DON'T HAVE TIME TO ASSESS.
YOU ASSESS ON THE RUN SO YEAH,
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT IS ON THE
OTHER SIDE.
YOU WORK OUT A PLAN BEFORE
HAND AND YOU ARE ANALYZING
YOUR STRAT STRAT ON --
STRATEGY ON THE RUN.
24 HOURS PASSED BEFORE THE
BODIES WERE REMOVED AND A LOT
OF INTENSE FORENSIC WORK WAS
GOING ON.
HELP US TO UNDERSTAND, WHAT IS
IT THAT THE POLICE ARE DOING
BEHIND THE CLOSED DOORS,
OBVIOUSLY NO CAMERAS ARE GOING
IN THERE AND NO ONE WILL GET
IN THERE IS IT EVAPORATE THAT
YOU TABE YOUR CRIME SCENE.
IT WAS A CONTAINED CRIME 69
AND BEHIND THE SCENES, THEY
ARE LOOKING AT THE PROCESS IN
THE CRIME SCENE AND FOREPSICS
THAT THEY ARE RECOVERING.
MATCHING THOSE ROUNDS TO THE
GUN.
THE MOST IMPORTANT THING IF
YOU ARE FINDING A ROUND.
AND NO GUN.
IS THERE A SECOND SHOOTER IN
THE BUILDING OR MAYBE -- OUT
IN THE WORLD.
THAT YOU KNOW, NOW IS STILL A
THREAT TO OTHERS.
YOU WANT TO MACH SURE THERE IS
ONE SHOOTER AND YOU HAVELET
EVIDENCE. AND MAKE SURE YOU
ESTABLISH A TIME LINE TO THAT.
OF COURSE, ONCE THE SHOOTER
KILL SAYS HIMSELF .
ALL OF THAT IS SECOND HARE TO
TABING ONE OR TWO SHOOTERSMENT
ONE FINAL QUESTION.
EALLY YOU HAVE BEEN A POLICE
OFFICER FOR A LONG TIME.
CAN EVER BE PREPARED TO SIGH
THE DEATH OF SO MANY CHILDREN?
>> I CAN'T FATHOM IT.
RIGHT NOW THEY HAVE
BEREAVEMENT CONTRACTORS AND
THAT IS IT NOT ONLY FOR THE
FAMILIES AND VICTIM A CHILDREN
BUT THE PARENTS AND SURVIVING
CHILDREN AND SCHOOL OFFICIALS
AND PLICE OFFICERS.
THEY ARE TRAUMATIZED.
THEY HAVE CHILDREN AT HOME.
AND SCHOOL OFFICIALS HAVE
CHILDREN AT HOME.
SURVIVOR'S GUILT.
YOU DIDN'T WANT THEM TO SEE
THEZ THIPPINGS.
NI HAVE TO SAY IT IS DIFFERENT
WITH TEEN IT IS OR ADULTINGS.
BUT IT LATELY IS.
NIT IS.
>> Y JUNE, MY HEART GOES OUT
TO ALL OF THE COPS.
THEY ARE HUMACHINE, TOO.
NWE PRAY THAT GOD GIVES THEM
TRENTH TO COPE WITH THE LOSS.
ING UP A FATHER WHOSE WAS
KILLED IN THE COLUMBINE
TRAGEDY.
WE'LL EXPLAIN.