>> Judge Jeanine: TONIGHT WE
ARE COMING TO YOU LIVE FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT WHICH
JUST YESTERDAY WAS THE SCENE
OF UNIMAGINABLE HORROR AND
GRIEF.
TODAY A COMMUNITY AND A NATION
STRUGGLE TO MAKE SENSE OF THE
INCOMPREHENSIBLE.
THE SENSELESS KILLING OF
INNOCENCE, CHILDREN AND THEIR
TEACHERS.
WE NOW KNOW THE NAMES OF ALL
20 CHILDREN AGES 6 AND 7 WHO
WERE MURDERED IN THEIR OWN
CLASSROOM.
THAT PLACE WHICH SHOULD BE A
HAVEN OF SAFETY IN A HEARTLESS
WORLD.
THEIR NAS SO MUCH LIKE THE
NAMES OF CHILDREN WE ALL KNOW,
12 GIRLS AND 8 BOYS.
CHARLOTTE AND DILLON, JESSE
AND EMILY TO NAME JUST A FEW.
AND JUST A LITTLE WHILE AGO,
WE HEARD FROM ROBBY PARKER THE
FATHER OF 6-YEAR-OLD EMILY,
ONE OF THE VICTIMS SHOT AND
KILLED YESTERDAY ALONG WITH 19
OF HER LITTLE CLASSMATES.
>> FIRST OF ALL, I WOULD
REALLY LIKE TO OFFER OUR
DEEPEST CONDOLENCES TO ALL THE
FAMILIES WHO WERE DIRECTLY
AFFECTED BY THIS SHOOTING.
IT'S A HORRIFIC TRAGEDY AND WE
WANT EVERYBODY TO KNOW THAT
OUR HEARTS AND OUR PRAYERS GO
OUT TO THEM.
>> Judge Jeanine: WE'RE ALSO
HEARING STORIES OF CHILDREN
WHO HELPED THEIR CLASSMATES
ESCAPE.
OF THE SCHOOL PRINCIPAL WHO
RUSHED THE GUNMAN IN AN EFFORT
TO PROTECT HER SCHOOL.
OF A TEACHER WHO PUT HERSELF
IN BETWEEN HER STUDENTS AND
THE GUNMAN TO PROTECT HER
STUDENTS.
BOTH LOSING THEIR LIVES.
AND TONIGHT WE'RE LEARNING
MORE ABOUT THE EVIL, MORE
APPROPRIATELY THE DEVIL WHO
TORE THROUGH THAT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
HELLO AND WELCOME TO THIS
SPECIAL EDITION OF JUSTICE.
WE ARE LIVE IN NEWTOWN
CONNECTICUT AND I'M JUDGE
JEANINE PIRRO.
THE POLICE DISPATCH AUDIO
TELLS THE CHILLING STORY AS
POLICE AND FIRST RESPONDERS
HEAR OF THE CARNAGE TAKING
PLACE AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> SANDY HOOK SCHOOL, CALLER
IS INDICATING SHE THINKS
SOMEONE IS SHOOTING IN THE
BUILDING.
>> RESPOND TO THE SANDY
>> Judge Jeanine: THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER DR. WAYNE CARVER HELD
A PRESS CONFERENCE A SHORT
TIME AGO GIVING US HORRIFYING
INSIGHT INTO WHAT HAPPENED AT
THAT SCHOOL IN THOSE LAST
MOMENTS.
OUR OWN MOLLY LINE WAS AT THAT
PRESS CONFERENCE.
MOLLY, TELL US WHAT HAPPENED.
>> THE MEDICAL EXAMINER
RELEASED A LOT OF DETAILS
TODAY AND THEY REALLY SPEAK OF
CLARITY WITH JUST HOW HORRIBLE
THIS SITUATION WAS.
HE ESSENTIALLY MADE VERY CLEAR
THAT THE VICTIM SUFFERED
MULTIPLE GUNSHOT WOUNDS AT THE
HANDS OF A LONG GUN, A RIFLE
HE CLARIFIED WHEN HE WAS ASKED
TO CLARIFY.
WE KNOW THAT HE PARTICIPATED
IN A NUMBER OF THOSE EXAMS
HIMSELF OF THE VICTIMS, OF
THESE LOVED ONES, AND THAT OF
THOSE HE EXAMINED THEY
SUFFERED 3 TO 11 GUNSHOT
WOUNDS.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT SUCH
LITTLE CHILDREN, THE YOUNGEST
VICTIMS 6 YEARS OLD, A BOY
NAMED NOAH, TINY, TINY PEOPLE
THAT WERE DESPERATELY TRYING
TO SAVE THEIR OWN LIVES AND
THESE WOMEN, SIX WOMEN GUNNED
DOWN THAT WERE TRYING TO SAVE
THE CHILDREN.
>> Judge Jeanine: YOU KNOW,
WHAT WAS INTERESTING IN THAT
PRESS CONFERENCE IS ALSO THE
FACT THAT HE SAID ALTHOUGH HE
IS A CHIEF MEDICAL EXAMINER,
THIS IS THE WORST THAT HE HAS
EVER SEEN.
>> HE SAYS HE HAS WORKED ABOUT
A THIRD OF A CENTURY IN HIS
LIFE DOING MEDICAL EXAMS.
THIS IS THE WORST HE HAS SEEN
AND THE WORST THAT ALL HIS
COLLEAGUES HAVE SEEN.
IT REALLY SPEAKS TO THE NATURE
OF THIS.
JUST HEARING ABOUT IT, WHAT WE
HAVE SEEN HERE ON THE SCENE,
THE EMOTION OF THE COMMUNITY,
BUT HE HAS PHYSICALLY SEEN IT
HIMSELF.
THEY ASKED IF HE HAD BROKEN
DOWN YET IF HE HAD CRIED
ABOUT.
THIS HE SAID SO FAR HE HASN'T.
HE SAID SO FAR HE HASN'T.
>> Judge Jeanine: CLEARLY A
BIG ISSUE WILL BE, YOU KNOW,
THE EMOTIONAL RESPONSE BY ALL
THESE FIRST RESPONDERS, POLICE
AND EVERYONE ELSE.
MOLLY, WE HEAR THAT THE
PRESIDENT IS COMING INTO TOWN
TOMORROW.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT
THAT?
>> THE DETAILS HAVEN'T BEEN
NAILED DOWN EXACTLY BUT
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS EXPECTED TO
MAKE A VISIT TO THE TOWN TO
PARTICIPATE IN AN INTERFAITH
VIGIL ESSENTIALLY PULL TOYING
THIS COMMUNITY.
SOME VIGILS HELD AGAINST THIS
COMMUNITY SINCE THE MASSACRE
HAS OCCURRED.
EVERYONE PULLING TOGETHER.
THE NEWTOWN HAS PULLED
TOGETHER.
THE SURROUNDING COMMUNITY HAS
PULLED TOGETHER.
THIS JUST SHOWS THAT THE
ENTIRE COUNTRY IS INVOLVED IN
WHAT'S HAPPENED HERE.
THIS IS A MUCH BIGGER TRAGEDY.
NOT JUST NEWTOWN AND NOT JUST
CONNECTICUT.
>> Judge Jeanine: ALL RIGHT,
MOLLY, THANKS SO MUCH.
MOLLY WILL BE ON THE SCENE
HERE TOMORROW CONTINUING WITH
HER COVERAGE.
AND NOW TO MIKE TOBIN WITH
REACTION FROM THE PEOPLE OF
THIS SMALL TOWN IN
CONNECTICUT.
MIKE?
>> AND, JUDGE, THIS IS A NIGHT
WHEN THE PAIN OF THIS TRAGEDY
IS REFRESHED.
AND THAT IS BECAUSE WE'RE
LEARNING NOW THE NAMES AND THE
FACES OF THE SMALLEST VICTIMS
OF THIS UNSPEAKABLE TRAGEDY.
NAMES LIKE 7-YEAR-OLD GRACE
MCDONALD WHOSE FAMILY SAID SHE
WAS THE LOVE AND LIFE OF THAT
FAMILY.
6-YEAR-OLD EMILY PARKER, WHO
SAID GOOD BY TO HER FATHER
BEFORE HE WENT OFF TO WORK.
>> SHE WOKE UP BEFORE I LEFT
AND I HAD ACTUALLY BEEN
TEACHING HER PORTUGUESE.
OUR LAST CONVERSATION WAS IN
PORTUGUESE.
AND SHE TOLD ME GOOD MORNING.
AND ASKED HOW I WAS DOING.
I SAID I WAS DOING WELL.
SHE SAID THAT SHE LOVED ME,
AND I GAVE HER A KISS AND I
WAS OUT THE DOOR.
>> SADLY FAMILIAR, THE
MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS ARE
POPPING UP AROUND TOWN WITH
CAN DIDS, TOYS, FLOWERS LAID
OUT.
THE PEOPLE HERE ARE DRAWING ON
THE BOND FORGED IN A SMALL
TOWN SO THEY CAN SOMEHOW
ENDURE THIS SADNESS.
>> I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO DO
BECAUSE WE HAVE NEVER BEEN
FACED WITH SOMETHING OF THIS
MAGNITUDE.
OUR FOCUS IS GIFT.
WE HAVE ENOUGH TIME DEALING
WITH IT AS ADULTS PROCESSING
ALL THE INFORMATION.
FOCUS ON THE KIDS AND TRY TO
GET THEM THROUGH THIS.
>> JUDGE, IF YOU LOOK BEHIND
ME YOU MAY NOTICE THAT THE
FLAG POLE IN THE CENTER OF
TOWN, THE FLAG IS AT
HALF-STAFF.
THERE IS SOMETHING MISSING
FROM THE CENTER OF TOWN.
THAT IS CHRISTMAS DECORATIONS.
A THE LO OF PEOPLE HERE FELT
IT JUST WASN'T APPROPRIATE TO
CELEBRATE IN THE FACE OF ALL
THIS TRAGEDY AND VOLUNTARILY
TOOK THE CHRISTMAS DECORATIONS
DOWN.
BACK TO YOU.
>> Judge Jeanine: HOW SAD.
MIKE TOBIN, THANKS SO MUCH.
WITH US NOW ON THE PHONE IS
ROBERT LACOTA WHOSE 6-YEAR-OLD
SON ADEN WAS IN SCHOOL
YESTERDAY.
HE ACTUALLY WITNESSED THE
SHOOTING OF HIS TEACHER VICKI
SOTO.
ROBERT, ARE YOU THERE?
>> YES.
HI.
>> Judge Jeanine: ALL RIGHT,
ROBERT.
THANKS SO MUCH FOR BEING WITH
US THIS EVENING.
TELL US ABOUT YOUR 6-YEAR-OLD.
WHAT DID HE SEE?
WHAT DID HE TELL YOU?
>> WELL, HE DID HEAR NOISES.
AND AT THAT POINT HIS TEACHER,
VICKI SOTO WHO IS A HERO IN
ALL OF OUR MINDS IS A
WONDERFUL TEACHER AND PERSON
HAD THE PRESENCE OF MIND TO
MAKE SURE THE CHILDREN WERE IN
A RELATIVELY SAFE AREA OF THE
ROOM AWAY FROM THE ENTRANCE OF
THE CLASSROOM THEY WERE
WAITING FOR SOMEONE TO COME.
AT THAT POINT THE GUNMAN BURST
INTO THE ROOM AND SHOT VICKI
SOTO AND THAT'S WHEN MORE
SHOTS WERE FIRED.
>> SHE WAS ACTUALLY -- SHE WAS
ACTUALLY SHOT IN FRONT OF YOUR
6-YEAR-OLD SON?
HE SAW THE SHOOTING?
>> CORRECT, YES, SHE DID.
>> AND WHAT IS HE TELLING YOU
NOW, ROBERT, ABOUT HOW H
FEELING AND HOW ARE YOU
DEALING WITH THIS?
>> WE'RE TRYING TO KEEP A
NORMAL ROUTINE.
WE'RE TRYING TO GET IN YOU
KNOW, BRUSH HIS TEETH AND GO
TO BED AT A REASONABLE TIME.
WE DO ASK HIM AND HE DOES ASK
QUESTIONS ABOUT THE BAD
PERSON.
AND YOU KNOW, YESTERDAY WAS
PARTICULARLY DIFFICULT.
HE WAS FEARFUL OF EVEN GOING
HOME AFTER WE LEFT THE
POLITICIAN.
YOU KNOW, HE -- LEFT THE
POLICE STATION.
HE IS GETTING BETTER BUT HE IS
STILL AFRAID OF BAD PEOPLE.
>> Judge Jeanine: ROBERT, I
ALSO UNDERSTAND THAT YOU HAVE
A 7-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER WHO WAS
IN THE CAFETERIA ACTUALLY IN
LEAVING THE SCHOOL SAW THE
BODIES OF THESE CHILDREN?
>> WELL, IT'S HER CLASSROOM
WAS NEAR THE CAFETERIA.
SHE WAS IN HER ROOM WITH HER
TEACHER AND FELLOW STUDENTS IN
A DIFFERENT SECTION OF THE
BUILDING ON -- YEAH.
BUT SHE DID AS I'M SURE MANY
OF THE CHILDREN DID BEAR
WITNESS TO VERY HORRIFIC
THINGS.
BUT, YEAH, SHE DID SEE SOME
BODIES THERE, YEAH.
>> Judge Jeanine: FINALLY, I
UNDERSTAND THAT YOUR SON
UNDERSTANDABLY, ADEN, WHO SAW
HIS TEACHER BEING SHOT, IS
RELUCTANT TO BE SEPARATED FROM
THE FAMILY OR FROM YOU.
I IMAGINE THAT THAT'S NOT
SURPRISING?
>> YEAH.
SO WE'RE, YOU KNOW, WE'RE
GOING -- WE'RE GETTING THROUGH
THIS WITH THE LOVE AND SUPPORT
OF OUR FAMILY AND OUR
NEIGHBORS.
WE'RE STAYING CLOSE.
THAT DOESN'T MEAN THAT TODAY
WE DID -- HE DID HAVE A PLAY
DATE WITH A GOOD FRIEND OF
HIS.
AT HIS FRIEND'S HOUSE.
SO AS LONG AS HE IS SOMEWHERE
WHERE HE FEELS SAFE, IT'S A
GOOD THING.
BUT MORE OFTEN THAN NOT HE
WANTS TO KNOW WE'RE CLOSE BY
AND WANTS TO STAY IN FAMILIAR
PLACES BUT, YEAH.
>> Judge Jeanine: CERTAINLY,
CERTAINLY UNDERSTANDABLE.
ROBERT, THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
SHARING THIS WITH US.
AND ALL OF OUR ENERGIES ARE
GOING TO YOU THIS EVENING AND
TO YOUR SON AS WELL.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Judge Jeanine: NOW I'M
JOINED ON THE PHONE BY STEVE.
WHOSE DAUGHTER DESCRIBED TO
HIM WHAT SHE HEARD OVER THE
LOUD SPEAKER FROM THE
PRINCIPAL'S OFFICE WHEN THE
SHOOTING BEGAN.
ARE YOU THERE, STEPHAN?
>> YEAH, HI, JUDGE.
HOW ARE YOU?
>> THANKS SO MUCH FOR BEING
WITH US THIS EVENING.
I AM WELL.
HOW ARE YOU?
HOW OLD IS YOUR 8-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHTER?
>> SHE IS DOING PRETTY GOOD.
SAMANTHA IS A STRONG WILLED
CHILD THANK GOD.
AND AT THIS MOMENT WE ARE
BLESSED MY WHOLE FAMILY HAS
BEEN BLESSED THAT SHE CAME OUT
OF THIS THING PHYSICALLY OKAY
BUT NATURALLY IT'S VERY VERY
VERY ROTTEN SITUATION TO BE IN
FOR ALL OF US.
IT'S BEEN VERY ROTTEN.
THINGS ARE GETTING BETTER.
>> Judge Jeanine: WHAT DID SHE
SAY SHE HEARD?
>> WHAT HAPPENED, SHE WAS IN
MRS. MARTIN'S CLASS AND THEY,
UNFORTUNATELY, IN THEIR
CLASSROOM DON'T HAVE A
BATHROOM OR ANY MEANS OF
HIDING OR ESCAPING IN ANY
CABINETS OR ANYTHING.
SOMEONE UNFORTUNATELY DID TRIP
THE LOUD SPEAKER SYSTEM AND
SHE HEARD CURSING COMING FROM
THE LOUD SPEAKER.
NOT CURSED KIDS KIND OF LOOKED
AROUND AND THEN THEY HEARD
TWO.
SHE HEARD TWO LARGE NOISES.
THAT'S WHEN MS. MARTIN WAS
JUST FABULOUS.
SHE BASICALLY GOT THE KID IN
THE CORNER AND MADE THEM
REMAIN THERE QUIETLY AND THEY
JUST WAITED IT OUT UNTIL THE
POLICE CAME.
>> STEPHAN, THIS WHOLE SIR
COUPLE STANCE, I MEAN, THIS
WHOLE SITUATION, WHEN DID YOU
HEAR ABOUT IT?
WHAT WAS THE FIRST THING YOU
HEARD AND WHAT WERE THE FIRST
THOUGHTS?
>> THE TOWN IS, AS EVERYBODY
HAS HEARD ACROSS THE COUNTRY
AND THE WORLD, THE TOWN IS
JUST A GREAT GREAT TOWN AND
WHAT MOST AMERICANS DON'T
UNDERSTAND SOMETHING LIKE THIS
NEVER HAPPENS, ESPECIALLY IN
OUR TOWN.
THEY NEED TO BE AWARE BUT
BASICALLY WE HAVE A REVERSED
911 SYSTEM RECALL ANY EVENTS
THAT HAPPENED.
AND IF YOU SEE THAT AND I
FIRST HEARD THAT THERE WAS A
POSSIBLE SHOOTING.
AND SO, KNOW, WHAT'S RUN
THROUGH YOUR MIND OBVIOUSLY
YOUR MIND JUST RACES AND YOUR
ADRENALINE GOES RIGHT TO YOUR
HEAD.
SO BASICALLY I WAS AT MY
OFFICE IN NEW YORK AND
OBVIOUSLY DROVE TOWARDS
NEWTOWN AND ONE OF MY FATHER'S
FRIENDS FRANK CALLED ME AND
ACTUALLY WAS LOCATING OUR
CHILDREN FOR US.
I HAD A SENSE OF RELIEF BEFORE
I ACTUALLY GOT THERE UNTIL I
ACTUALLY SAW HER I WASN'T
SATISFIED.
>> Judge Jeanine: ALL RIGHT.
STEPHAN DELGIUDICE THANK YOU
SO MUCH FOR SHARING.
OUR LOVE GOES OUT TO YOU AND
YOUR FAMILY AS WELL.
AMAZING STORIES FROM INSIDE
THE SCHOOL.
A TEACHER TELLS US ABOUT THE
STUDENTS THAT HE LOST.
HEYYY, YOU'RE
GOING OUT LIKE THAT?
YEAH, WHY?
WELL, WHAT WOULD
THE NEIGHBORS THINK?
I SEE YOU!
C'MON, GET MISTER FEATHER!
LOOK WHAT I HAVE.
MISTER BIRD. REMEMBER?
QUACK QUACK QUACK!
WE'RE JUST PLAYING!
I'M TRYING TO
GET YOU OUT OF THERE!
EVEN STILL...
Announcer: YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE
PERFECT TO BE A PERFECT PARENT.
THERE ARE THOUSANDS OF TEENS
IN FOSTER CARE
WHO DON'T NEED PERFECTION,
THEY NEED YOU.
>> EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY
TODAY.
>> A CALL CAME INTO DISPATCH,
POLICE OFFICERS AND RESOURCES
FROM ALL OVER THE STATE RACED
TO THAT AREA AS THEY CONVERGED
ON THE SCHOOL.
>> THE CHILDREN OBVIOUSLY WERE
VERY SHAKEN.
THEY WERE CRYING IN THE
CLOSET.
WHEN THEY WERE LEAVING, THE
POLICE MADE THEM HOLD HANDS
AND TOLD THEM TO CLOSE THEIR
EYES.
>> THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS.
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
>> MY GYM TEACHER DIRECTED US
TO STAY AGAINST THE WALL.
EVERYBODY STARTED KIND OF
PANICKING.
>> THERE IS NO WORDS.
IT'S SHEAR TERROR.
>> DOESN'T EVEN SEEM REAL.
IT JUST DOES NOT SEEM LIKE
IT'S EVEN POSSIBLE.
>> WE ALL HUDDLED AND I KEPT
HEARING THESE BOOMING NOISES.
[SIREN]
>> I JUST ALL OF US MOMS
NETWORKING TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT WHAT'S GOING ON.
>> KIDS WERE TERRIFIED.
THEY WERE TERRIFIED.
THEY HAD JUST WITNESSED
SOMETHING AND THEY WERE
TERRIFIED.
>> MOST TRAUMATIZING THING I
HAVE EVER BEEN THROUGH.
>> MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF
THE VICTIMS AND IN THE WORDS
OF STRICTER HEAL THE BROKEN
HEARTED AND BIND UP THEIR
WOUNDS.
>> Judge Jeanine: RAY HORVATH
IS THE HEAD TEACHER FOR THE
SCHOOL AGE PROGRAM FOR THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
FOUR, FOUR OF HIS STUDENTS
WERE KILLED YESTERDAY.
RAY HIMSELF HAD LEFT THE
SCHOOL JUST MINUTES BEFORE THE
BLOOD SHED.
HE JOINS ME NOW ON THE PHONE.
RAY?
>> YEP?
>> ARE YOU THERE, RAY?
>> YES, I AM.
>> THANKS SO MUCH FOR BEING
WITH US THIS EVENING.
TELL US ABOUT THIS PROGRAM
THAT YOU RUB.
WHAT IS THE SCHOOL AGE
PROGRAM?
>> IT PROVIDES A SERVICE TO
THE PARENTS.
PARENTS WHO HAVE TO DROP KIDS
OFF EARLY.
OBVIOUSLY YOU DON'T HAVE
BABYSITTERS AT 7:00 IN THE
MORNING.
PARENTS WHO COME HOME LATE AT
NIGHT NEED TO PARK THEIR KIDS
SOMEWHERE.
SO WE PROVIDE TUTORING, WE
HELP THEM WITH THEIR HOMEWORK.
WE PROVIDE, THERE IS IS
VARIOUS COMPONENTS TO IT
LITERACY COMPONENT ARTS AND
CRAFTS.
WE FILL UP THERE BEFORE AND
AFTER SCHOOL HOURS.
>> ALL RIGHT.
SO THEN YESTERDAY MORNING, YOU
WERE WITH THESE KIDS IN THE
PROGRAM WHOSE PARENTS DROPPED
THEM OFF AT SCHOOL BEFORE
SCHOOL STARTS.
AND YOU LEFT BEFORE THE
SHOOTING STARTED.
WERE YOU AT ALL FAMILIAR WITH
THE SHOOTER, I MEAN HAD YOU
EVEN HEARD HIS NAME BEFORE?
>> I'M SORRY, I JUST.
>> Judge Jeanine: YOU NEVER
HEARD OF HIM.
>> I DON'T THINK ANYONE IN
TOWN IS QUITE FAMILIAR.
NOW SEARCH FAMILIAR WITH HIM.
>> Judge Jeanine: ALL RIGHT.
RAY, LET ME GO RIGHT TO THE
FOUR STUDENTS THAT WERE KILLED
OF YOURS.
DID YOU SEE THEM YESTERDAY
MORNING?
WHAT WAS YESTERDAY LIKE AT
SCHOOL?
>> VERY ORDINARY DAY, VERY
ORDINARY.
A LOT OF FUN.
I LOVE KIDS.
WE HAVE A LOT OF FUN WITH
THEM.
YEAH, I THINK ALL FOUR WERE
WITH US YESTERDAY MORNING.
[CLEARING THROAT]
>> I'M SORRY, IT'S STILL
PRETTY FRESH.
SO I GET A LITTLE CHOKED UP.
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> Judge Jeanine: OF COURSE
YOU DO.
RAY, VERY QUICKLY WE'RE COMING
UP ON HARD BREAK HERE.
IT WAS NORMAL DAY FOR THE
FOUR?
>> YEAH.
SENT THEM OFF.
ONCE THE BUSES ARRIVED, WE
TRANSFER THEM WE SEND THEM OUT
OF THE ROOM AND TO THEIR
CLASSROOMS.
THEY JOIN THE CROWD COMING.
IN AND WE STAYED, WE USUALLY
GET OUT AT 9, I MEAN 9:15,
9:20.
WE STAYED A LITTLE LATE.
YOU KNOW.
>>
>> RAY, THANKS SO MUCH FOR
BEING WITH US THIS EVENING.
>>
>> YOU ARE WELCOME.
>> Judge Jeanine: HOW THE
KILLER GOT INTO THE SCHOOL.
[ Male Announcer ]
RED LOBSTER'S
HITTING THE STREETS
TO TELL REAL PEOPLE ABOUT
OUR NEW 15 UNDER $15 MENU.
OH MY GOODNESS!
OH MY GOSH,
THIS LOOKS AMAZING!
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR NEW MAINE STAYS!
15ENTREES UNDER $15,
SEAFOOD, CHICKEN AND MORE!
OOTHE TILAPIAWITH ROASTEDEGETAB!
I'M ACTUALLY LOOKING AT
THE WO GRILLED CHICKEN
WITH PORTOBELLO WINE SAUCE.
AT PORK CHOP
WAS GREAT!
NO MORE
FAST FOOD FRIDAY'S!
WE'RE GOING TO GO
TO RED LOBSTER.
YEP.
[ Male Announcer ]
COME TRY OUR NEW MENU
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
SALAD, SANDWICHES, AND MORE.
YOU WANNA SEE  WALMART HAS
SIMILAR GIFTS FOR LESS?
YEAH.
LET'S GO.
SAMSUNG GALAXY S3 --
OVER FIFTY DOLLARS LESS
THAN BEST BUY!
WOW! FIFTY BUCKS!
YEAH!
THAT'S A PAIR OF SHOES.
SEE FOR YOURSELF IF YOU COULD
SAVE ON THEIFTS YOU WANT.
WALMART.
often comes with a set
of equally impressive
instructions ?
Shouldn't something
that's truly advanced,
not need much explanation
at all ?
With the Nokia Lumia 822
on Verizon,
there's not much to learn
because it's
powered by Windows...
to let you do more than you ever
imagined on your smartphone.
Exclusively with Data Sense--
a feature that makes
the most of your plan.
Only on Verizon.
>> WE HAVE ESTABLISHED THE
POINT OF ENTRY.
I CAN TELL YOU IT HE WAS NOT
VOLUNTARILY LET INTO THE
SCHOOL AT ALL.
THAT HE FORCED HIS WAY INTO
THE SCHOOL.
THAT'S AS FAR AS WE CAN GO ON
THAT.
>> Judge Jeanine: YESTERDAY'S
MASSACRE WAS JUST THE LATEST
INCIDENT OF SCHOOL VIOLENCE
THAT WE HAVE SEEN IN THIS
COUNTRY.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
HAD SAFETY MEASURES IN PLACE,
BUT THE SHOOTER WAS STILL ABLE
TO GAIN ENTRY WHICH RAISES THE
QUESTION HOW SAFE ARE OUR
SCHOOLS AND HOW SAFE ARE OUR
CHILDREN?
WITH ME IS FAIRFIELD COUNTY
POLICE CHIEF GARY MCNAMARA.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US.
>> THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
>> YOU ARE A POLICE CHIEF JUST
30 MILES FROM HERE.
>> JUST A LITTLE SOUTH OF
NEWTOWN, YEAH.
>>
>> Judge Jeanine: YOU ARE
FAMILIAR WITH THE ISSUE OF
SCHOOL VIOLENCE AND SCHOOL
SAFETY IN CONNECTICUT.
>> I AM.
>> CONNECTICUT IS A SMALL
STATE.
SO YOU KNOW THE CHIEFS OF
POLICE IN THE AREA REALLY GET
TOGETHER.
SO ANY TIME ANYTHING HAPPENS
WE REALLY DO COME TOGETHER AND
DISSECT IT TOGETHER.
>> Judge Jeanine: CHIEF, WHAT
IS MANDATED.
IS CONNECTICUT, IS THERE
ANYTHING THAT'S REQUIRED OF
THIS STATE?
>> THERE IS, ALL SCHOOLS HAVE
TO HAVE A CRISIS PLAN IN
PLACE.
AND THEN EVERY THREE MONTHS
AFTER COLUMBINE HIGH SCHOOL IN
2000, THEY HAVE TO -- EVERY
THREE MONTHS PUT THAT PLAN
INTO PLACE.
THE SCHOOL SUPERINTENDENT, THE
SCHOOL ADMINISTRATORS HAVE TO
WORK WITH LOCAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT EVERY THREE
MONTHS.
SORT OF LIKE A FIRE DRILL TO
IMPLEMENT THE PLAN TO ENSURE
--
>> -- I UNDERSTAND THAT THESE
CHILDREN ACTUALLY HAD GONE
THROUGH SOME OF THE FIRE
DRILLS AND THEY HAD DONE THAT.
BUT THE ISSUE OF SAFETY AND
THE THREAT ASSESSMENT, I MEAN,
DOES THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT
MANDATE THAT EVERY SCHOOL HAVE
A THREAT ASSESSMENT DONE
REGARDING SAFETY?
>> WELL, I THINK THERE IS SOME
SORT OF A MANDATE.
AND I'M NOT REALLY FAMILIAR
WITH HOW HEAVY THAT MANDATE
IS.
BUT I THINK GIVEN THE
ATMOSPHERE.
IT'S A PUBLIC MANDATE.
YOU HAVE TO HAVE A THREAT
ASSESSMENT IN EACH SCHOOL.
>> Judge Jeanine: WHO DECIDES,
CHIEF, HOW MUCH SAFETY IS
IMPLEMENTED AT A PARTICULAR
SCHOOL.
>> I THINK IT DEPENDS ON THE
SCHOOL DISTRICT.
IT DEPENDS ON THE LAW
ENFORCEMENT AND THE DESIGN OF
THE SCHOOL.
HOW OLD THE SCHOOLS ARE.
>> Judge Jeanine: IT'S REALLY
THE LOCALS WHO DECIDE THIS?
>> IT COMES DOWN FROM THE
STATE.
SCHOOL DISTRICTS CAN GO TO THE
STATE POLICE AND GO TO THE
STATE FOR THREAT ASSESSMENT.
>> Judge Jeanine: ALL RIGHT.
AND FINALLY THIS IS NOT THE
FIRST TIME THAT THIS STATE HAS
DEALT WITH THE ISSUE OF SCHOOL
VIOLENCE.
>> IT HAS NOT.
WE HAVE EXPERIENCED SOMETHING
IN FAIRFIELD BACK IN 2
CLASSROOM FULL OF STUDENTS
HELD HOSTAGE FOR A PERIOD OF 8
HOURS.
THANKFULLY NOBODY WAS INJURED
AS THE CASE HERE.
IT TOUCHES ALL OF US.
CONNECTICUT IS A SMALL STATE.
WE ARE ALL HERE HELPING
TOGETHER.
>> Judge Jeanine: UNFORTUNATELY
WE HAD MANY DIE IN JUST OVER
THE WOODS BEHIND ME RIGHT NOW.
CHIEF, FINALLY, VERY QUICKLY,
DO YOU THINK THAT THIS COULD
HAVE BEEN PREVENTED?
>> YOU KNOW, GIVEN THE MINIMUM
FACTS I HAVE, I DON'T THINK IT
COULD HAVE BEEN PREVENTED.
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> I THINK WE HAVE SAVED A LOT
MORE KIDS THAN WOULD HAVE BEEN
DONE IF THERE WERE NO PLANS IN
PLACE.
>> I THINK WE HAVE GOT TO WORK
A LITTLE HARDER THOUGH.
CHIEF MCNAMARA THANK YOU FOR
BEING WITH US THIS EVENING.
>> THANK YOU.
>> COMING UP:  WHO WAS THIS
SHOOTER WHO LITERALLY
UNLEASHED HELL AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
COMING UP INSIDE THE MIND OF A
KILLER.
There is no
mass-produced human.
So we created the
extraordinarily
comfortable Sleep Number
Experience.
around a bed with DualAir
Technology that allows you
to adjust to the support
your body needs - each of
your bodies.
Our sleep professionals will
help you find
your sleep number setting.
Exclusively at a Sleep
Number store.
Sleep Number.
Comfort individualized.
This holiday season, give
the gift that's magical:
the innovative AirFit
adjustable pillow at
special 30% savings.
>> HE WAS DIFFERENT, HE WAS
QUIET.
NICE KID.
GOOD KID.
I MEAN, HE WAS DEFINITELY
CHALLENGE THE FAMILY IN THAT
HOUSE.
EVERY FAMILY HAS ONE.
I HAVE ONE.
THEY HAVE ONE.
BUT NEVER IN TROUBLE WITH THE
LAW.
NEVER IN TROUBLE WITH
ANYTHING.
I KNOW SHE HAD ISSUES WITH
SCHOOL.
SHE EVENTUALLY WOUND UP HOME
SCHOOLING HIM.
SHE BATTLED WITH THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT.
IN WHAT CAPACITY I'M NOT 100%
CERTAIN IF IT WAS BEHAVIOR OR
LEARNING DISABILITIES, I
REALLY DON'T KNOW BUT IS HE A
VERY VERY BRIGHT BOY.
HE IS SMART.
>> Judge Jeanine: IT DOESN'T
MAKE SENSE.
A LOT OF QUESTIONS ABOUT THE
SHOOTER.
BUT I HAVE TO TELL YOU MY
BACKGROUND, I'M REALLY NOT SO
INTERESTED IN THE MENTAL STATE
OF THE SHOOTER.
I'M INTERESTED IN THE VICTIM.
I'M INTERESTED IN THE PEOPLE
WHO NEVER CHOSE TO BE A VICTIM
IN THE FIRST PLACE AS OPPOSED
TO GUY WHO MAKES A A DECISION
TO DRESS UP IN BLACK GARB AND
A MILITARY VEST AND TAKE A
LONG GUN AND TWO
SEMIAUTOMATICS AND COME INTO
THE SCHOOL WHERE THE MOST
VULNERABLE VICTIMS IN OUR
SOCIETY ARE AND TAKE THEIR
LIVES.
TO ME, THE ISSUE OF THE STATE
OF MIND OF THE CRIMINAL IS NOT
SO MUCH ABOUT HIS STATE OF
MIND BUT ABOUT HIS CHOICE.
HE IS THE ONE WHO CHOSE TO
PICK UP A GUN.
MAKE A DECISION TO KILL.
BUT HAVING SAID THAT, MY
PROSECUTOR BACKGROUND I WILL
NOW PUT ON HOLD AND I WILL ASK
AND FIRST OF ALL INTRODUCE
DR. JOHN SHARP, WHO IS A
PSYCHIATRIST ON THE FACULTY OF
THE HARVARD MEDICAL SCHOOL,
DR. SHARP, SO GOOD TO HAVE YOU
HERE.
YOU HEARD ME RAMP, I DON'T
MUCH CARE ABOUT THIS GUY'S
STATE OF MIND.
I CARE ABOUT THE VICTIMS.
THE VICTIM'S FAMILY THE RIPPLE
EFFECT.
THE FACT THAT THIS TOWN WILL
FOREVER BEAR THE INSIGNIFICANT
ANY I CAN'T INSIGNIA THAT
HAPPENS HERE.
>> LET'S TALK ABOUT GRIEVING
AND.
>> I'M A PARENT.
I DROP THEM OFF AT THAT SCHOOL
BECAUSE I THOUGHT THEY WOULD
LEARN TO BE SAFE.
WHAT AM I FEELING RIGHT NOW?
>> YOU ARE FEELING ANGRY.
YOU ARE FEELING SCARED.
YOU ARE FEELING SO MANY
DIFFERENT EMOTIONS IT'S HARD
TO KEEP THEM STRAIGHT.
EVERYONE WOKE UP TODAY TO THE
WORST NIGHTMARE TO EVEN
IMAGINE THAN WHEN THEY WENT TO
BED LAST NIGHT.
WHAT PARENTS HAVE TO DO IS
PROVIDE A SENSE OF SAFETY FOR
THEIR CHILDREN.
>> Judge Jeanine: BUT THEY
DIDN'T.
DO THEY LIVE WITH GUILT?
HOW DO THEY RESOLVE WHAT THEY
HAVE GONE THROUGH?
HOW DO THEY PROTECT THEIR OWN
CHILDREN.
>> WHAT WE KNOW TWO DIFFERENT
THINGS.
THAT DOESN'T MAKE US FEEL
BETTER OR SAFE WHEN WE
CONSIDER DROPPING OUR KID
SOMEWHERE OR GOING TO A MALL.
WE HAVE TO REMEMBER THAT WE
CAN SUPPORT ONE ANOTHER AND
RECREATE A SENSE OF SAFETY.
AND MAKE SURE THE KIDS FEEL
THAT WAIT A MINUTE KIDS CAN BE
MORE RESILIENT THAN ADULTS
EVEN.
>> Judge Jeanine: I HE AGREE KIS
ARE MORE RESILIENT.
WE JUST SPOKE WITH A FATHER
WHOSE 6-YEAR-OLD IS AFRAID TO
HAVE HIM LEAVE HIM SIDE.
>> THAT'S A NORMAL RESPONSE.
RESPOND TO WHAT YOU ARE SEEING
IN YOUR CHILDREN.
IT'S DIFFERENT IF YOU ARE
TALKING TO A 6-YEAR-OLD OR A
PRETEEN OR TEEN.
6-YEAR-OLD IS VERY CONCRETE.
YOU WANT TO SEE THOUSAND THEY
ARE FEELING.
MAKE SURE THEY FEEL SAFE.
OBSERVE THEM AND COMFORT THEM.
PRETEENS GET CAUGHT UP IN
MORALITY.
VERY BLACK AND WHITE.
MAKE SURE THEY ARE THINKING
RIGHT.
>> Judge Jeanine: WHAT ABOUT
THE KIDS WHO ARE WATCHING
TELEVISION AND SHOULD PARENTS
TAKE ADVANTAGE OF THIS
SITUATION TO TALK TO THEIR
CHILDREN AND SAY THIS IS WHAT
YOU SHOULD DO OR THIS IS, YOU
KNOW, WHAT HAPPENS IN THE
WORLD?
>> ESPECIALLY THEY ARE TEENAGE
YEARS.
THE YOUNGER I THINK LESS
EXPOSURE THE BETTER.
ALL OF US CAN OVERDOSE ON
TELEVISION.
WE SHOULDN'T OVERDO IT IN ANY
WAY.
WE SHOULDN'T OVERDRINK OR
EXERCISE OR ISOLATE.
WE SHOULD TRY TO BE MOD
DEMOCRAT AND IN COMMUNICATION
WITH ONE ANOTHER AND OPEN TO
RECEIVE WHATEVER SUPPORT IS
GOING TO HELP US.
COUNSELORS, RELIGIOUS SUPPORT.
ONE ANOTHER.
>> WELL, OKAY.
AND THEN WHAT HAPPENS WITH THE
CHILDREN AND THE PARENTS WHO
CLEAR LIVE WILL GO INTO A
DEPRESSION?
>> WELL, THAT CAN BE TREATED.
SO I DON'T THINK WE SHOULD
THINK THAT THAT'S A FAILURE.
WE DON'T THINK OF THAT OF ANY
KIND OF A SHORT OR MORAL
UPCOMING.
THAT'S VERY TREATABLE.
WE ARE NOT TALKING ABOUT THE
SHOOTER HERE.
HE PLAY HAVE HAD A CONDITION
TOO.
ANYBODY SUFFERING NOW CAN BE
TREATED AND MOVE TOWARD
HEALING.
>> Judge Jeanine: FINAL
QUESTION BEFORE I GO TO
DR. BARBARA KERWIN A FORENSIC
PSYCHOLOGIST SITTING IN NEW
YORK CITY NOW.
YOU KNOW, WHEN WE SAY CAN THIS
KIND OF THING BE PREVENTED AND
YOU THINK THAT MAYBE IT CAN
BE, IF YOU KNOW ENOUGH ABOUT
THE INDIVIDUAL.
YOU KNOW, MY QUESTION REALLY
IS WHY IS THE WORLD SO
DIFFERENT TODAY?
WHY ARE PEOPLE DOING THIS?
WHY IS THIS BECOMING THE NORM?
>> YOU KNOW, I DON'T HAVE THE
ONE ANSWER FOR THAT.
PEOPLE THINK THAT THERE IS A
TOO MUCH OF CULTURE OF
VIOLENCE.
PEOPLE ARE TOO ISOLATED IN
THEIR OWN MINDS.
THE MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEM ISN'T
AS GOOD AS IT SHOULD BE.
LOVING EMBRACE THAT INSISTED
ON THERAPY OF A MEANINGFUL
SORT THAT HE COULD HAVE
ACCESSED AND AFFORD COULD HAVE
AVOIDED THIS.
>> DOCTOR, THANKS SO MUCH FOR
BEING WITH US THIS EVENING.
KNOW, DOCTOR, YOU RAN THE UNIT
FOR THE VIOLENT CRIMINALLY
INSANE AT CREED MORE.
SO YOU HAVE GOT A LOT OF
EXPERIENCE WITH THIS KIND OF
THING.
WERE THERE A TELL TALE SIGNS
OR ARE THERE PREDICTABLE
ISSUES OR FACTORS THAT WOULD
IDENTIFY THIS INDIVIDUAL AS A
DANGEROUS INDIVIDUAL.
>> WHAT WE'RE SEEING WITH HIM
IS THE STORY THAT WE SEE AGAIN
AND AGAIN WITH THESE COINS OF
CREEPY PEOPLE THAT GO IN AND
UNLEASH THIS TYPE OF VIOLENCE.
HE WAS THE LONER, HE DIDN'T
GET ALONG WITH OTHER PEOPLE.
HE HAD ISSUES IN SCHOOL.
HE WAS BRILL YENT.
BRIGHT AND SOMETHING WAS
DISTURBLILY WRONG AND NOBODY
SEEMED TO TAKE NOTICE OF IT
UNTIL WE HAVE THE UNTHINKABLE.
IT'S NOT SO UNTHINKABLE WHEN
WE HAVE A UNBALANCED PARANOID
ANGRY ISOLATED INDIVIDUAL.
IS HE REALLY FOLLOWING THE
PATTERN OF THAT PARANOID TYPE.
WE HAD JAMES HOLMES OUT IN
AURORA, COLORADO.
A SIMILAR KIND OF PERSONALITY.
AND MY ISSUE IS WHEN ARE WE
GOING TO BECOME AWARE OF THIS?
WHEN ARE WE GOING TO
INTERVENE?
>> Judge Jeanine: DOCTOR, IS
THERE ANY WAY FOR US AS A
SOCIETY TO SAY THIS GUY IS A
LONER, WE BETTER CHECK HIM
OUT?
LOOK, WHEN I WAS A JUDGE, THEY
BRING PEOPLE IN FLONT OF ME
AND SAY HE IS DANGER TO THE
COMMUNITY OR HIMSELF I DO A
PSYCHIATRIC ON HIM.
THIEVES ARE YOWNEL MALES IN
THEIR 20 WE ARE TALKING '.
AURORA, ALL OF THE OTHER
SHOOTINGS AND COLUMBINE AND
ALL OF THAT.
HOW DO WE CATCH THESE PEOPLE.
>> THEY ARE NOT ISOLATED
COMPLETELY A COMMUNITY OF ONE.
NOW THEY ARE KNOW OF PEOPLE
WHO KILLED THIS YOUNG MAN.
HE BASS POOR THE.
I DIDN'T BEHAVE CORRECTLY.
THAT'S WHEN WE NEED TO NOTICE.
THAT'S WHEN WE NEED TO SAY HE
NEEDS TO BE EXAMINED.
HE NEEDS HELP.
MORE STATES THAN NOT HAVE
ASSISTED OUTPATIENT TREATMENT
PROGRAMS.
WE CAN INSIST THAT PEOPLE WHO
SHOW WEIRDNESS, PROCLIVITIES
TRARDZ VIOLENCE, SOCIAL
ISOLATION, BIZARRE THINKING.
>> Judge Jeanine: YOU KNOW
WHAT, DOCTOR, WITH ALL DUE
RESPECT AND YOU ARE CERTAINLY
A WELL RESPECTED DOCTOR AS IS
DR. SHARP.
THIS KID WAS HOME COOD.
THERE HAS GOT TO BE SOMETHING
BECAUSE HIS MOTHER WANTED TO
HOME SCHOOL HIM.
>> WHY DID SHE WANT TO HOME
SCHOOL HIM?
WHAT WAS GOING WRONG?
YOU DON'T PICK A KID OUT OF
SCHOOL AND HOME SCHOOL HIM IF
EVERYTHING IS ROSY FOR HIM IN
SCHOOL UNLESS YOU HAVE A
RELIGIOUS PERSUASION.
>> WHY DID THE MOTHER AND, OF
COURSE, DR. CORWIN AND
DR. SHARP.
WHY DID THE HIS OR HER HAVE
THOSE SEMIAUTOMATICS ON THE
BUSH BLASTER.
BARB SHARP.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US.
THE SHOOTER HAD ACCESS TO AN
ARSENAL EVER WEAPONS.
WHERE DID HE GET THEM AND WHY
DID HE USE THEM?
STAY WITH US.
[ sniffs ] I HAVE A COLD.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
♪
MANY HOT DOGS
ARE WITHIN YOU.
TRY PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO,
IT'S THE POWER OF PEPTO,
BUT IT FITS IN YOUR POCKET.
NOW TELL THE WORLD
DANIEL...
OF PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO.
>> ALL THE WOUNDS THAT I KNOW
OF AT THIS POINT WERE CAUSED
BY THE LONG WEAPON.
THIS TYPE OF WEAPON IS NOT --
THE BULLETS ARE DESIGNED IN
SUCH A FASHION THAT THE
ENERGY, THIS IS VERY CLINICAL.
I SHOULDN'T BE SAYING.
THIS THE ENERGY IS DEPOSITED
IN THE TISSUE SO THE BULLETS
[INAUDIBLE]
>> Judge Jeanine: JOINING ME
NOW WITH MARK FUHRMAN, FOX
NEWS CONTRIBUTOR AND SOMEONE
WHO LIKE ME, HAS BEEN AT MANY
CRIME SCENES INVOLVING YOUNG
CHILDREN.
MARK, ARE YOU THERE?
>> I AM HERE.
>> Judge Jeanine: MARK, I SEE
YOU NOW.
ALL RIGHT, MARK, LOOK, THERE
IS NO QUESTION THAT THE DEVIL
HAD BEEN IN NEWTOWN
CONNECTICUT.
YOU AND I HAVE SEEN OUTCOME
CHILDREN IN HOMICIDE SCENES.
IT IS SOMETHING THAT NOTHING
CAN PREPARE YOU FOR.
BUT THE NUMBER OF CHILDREN IN
THIS SITUATION.
THE NUMBER OF CHILDREN DEAD
AND AS WE HEARD FROM THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER WITH MULTIPLE
WOUNDS HAS TO BE DIFFICULT FOR
THE MOST SEASONED HOMICIDE
DETECTIVE AND THE FIRST
RESPONDERS.
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THAT, MARC?
>> I SAY IT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
IT'S ONE THING THAT YOU DEAL
WITH, SOME OF THE PEOPLE THAT
COMMIT THEIR LIFE TO CRIME.
GANG MEMBERS.
PEOPLE WHO COMMIT TO VIOLENCE.
THEY END UP GETTING SHOT OR
INJURED.
THAT'S ONE THING EVEN A
DOMESTIC SITUATION IS
DIFFERENT INNOCENT CHILDREN.
NOBODY PREPARED FOR.
THIS THE ONLY SCENES THAT I
REALLY REMEMBER THAT I CAN
NEVER ERASE, ONE IS A
4-YEAR-OLD LITTLE GIRL THAT
I'LL NEVER FORGET.
SO, NO, IT NEVER GOES AWAY.
AND THE ONLY WAY YOU DO IS YOU
JUST DETACH YOURSELF AND GET
YOUR JOB DONE AND TRY TO GET
OUT OF THERE.
>> Judge Jeanine: WE BOTH KNOW
IS WHAT YOU DO IS YOU CLOSE
YOUR MIND OFF EMOTIONALLY.
YOU BECOME THE DETECTIVE, I
BECOME THE D.A.
BUT IN THE QUIET OF THE NIGHT,
MARK, YOU AND I BOTH KNOW THAT
SCENE COMES BACK TO US OVER
AND OVER AGAIN.
NOW, MARC, I HAVE SPECIFICALLY
NOT MENTIONED THE NAME OF THE
SHOOTER.
I WOULDN'T GIVE HIM THAT.
I WOULDN'T GIVE HIM ANYTHING
OTHER THAN WHAT HE DESERVES IF
HE WERE TO LIVE.
BUT, WHAT DO WE DO ABOUT THE
FACT THAT WE HAVE GOT SCHOOLS
WHERE OUR CHILDREN ARE THAT
WE'RE NOT ABLE TO PROTECT
THEM?
I MEAN, WHAT DO MOST SCHOOLS
HAVE?
SHOULD THERE BE ARMED GUARDS
AT OUR SCHOOLS IN THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS?
WHAT DO YOU THINK SHOULD
HAPPEN?
>> WELL, WE ADDRESS TERRORISM
BY TRYING TO FORTIFY OR MAKE
SOFT TARGETS HARD TARGETS.
THAT'S REALLY WHAT WE NEED TO
DO.
EVERYTHING ELSE CAN COME AFTER
THAT.
BUT YOU NEED TO MAKE IT AS
DIFFICULT AS POSSIBLE FOR
SOMEBODY THAT'S NOT AUTHORIZED
TO GET INTO ANY SCHOOL.
THAT IS THE FIRST STEP.
UNTIL THAT STEP IS MET, THEN
YOU CAN'T GO FORWARD WITH A
PLAINED CLOTHES POLICE OFFICER
OR SECURITY ANYTHING ELSE
EVEN TRAINING SOME OF THE
TEACHER WHAT IS TO DO.
YOU HAVE TO FIRST MAKE A
BARRICADE.
AND MAKE IT A HARDER TARGET
BECAUSE RIGHT NOW EVERY
SUSPECT THAT WANTS TO COMMIT
THIS TYPE OF VIOLENCE KNOWS
THAT THEY WILL GET ON THE
PROPERTY AND THEY WILL GET
INSIDE.
>> WELL, AND THAT'S THE HARD
PART.
BUT YOU KNOW MAYBE WE NEED TO
LEARN FROM THE SCHOOLS IN
ISRAEL.
SCHOOLS IN IRELAND WHO HAVE
ALL TAKEN PRECAUTIONS FOR
THEIR CHILDREN AND, YOU KNOW,
WE LIVE IN A FREE SOCIETY.
I DON'T KNOW IF THERE IS ANY
WAY TO PROTECT AGAINST.
THIS MARK FUHRMAN THANKS SO
MUCH FOR BEING WITH US THIS
EVENING.
>> THANK YOU, JUDGE.
>> Judge Jeanine: COMING UP,
WE HAVE ALL HAD OUR FAITH
SHANE BY THE EVIL THAT
CONFRONTED US YESTERDAY IN THE
FORM OF A 20-YEAR-OLD IN BLACK
FATIGUES AND A MILITARY STYLE
VET.
AFTER THE BREAK, WHAT CAN WE
DO TO COME TO GRIPS WITH THIS
HORRIFIC TRAGEDY?
>> THE PAIN IN THIS TOWN IS
PALPABLE.
THE DEVIL WAS HERE YESTERDAY.
HOW DOES ONE EVEN BEGIN TO
HEAL AFTER THE PHYSICAL AND
THE EMOTIONAL TRAUMA THAT SO
MANY EXPERIENCED.
DONNA MORSI IS A SPOKESPERSON
WITH THE RED CROSS.
ALSO WITH ME IS SPARTICUS AND
HIS HANDLER BRAD.
DONNA, I UNDERSTAND THAT YOU
CAME IN FROM BOSTON AS SOON AS
YOU HEARD ABOUT THIS.
LET ME SAY ONE THING ABOUT THE
RED CROSS, WE LOST OUR HOME IN
UPSTATE NEW YORK.
THE RED CROSS WAS THERE AND
BROUGHT FOOD TO US.
WE HADN'T EATEN IN A WHILE AND
I WANT THANK YOU ON BEHALF OF
SO MANY PEOPLE.
BUT WHAT DID YOU SEE, HEAR
COMPARED TO SOME OF THIS
STUFF, WHO HORRIFIC STUFF I'M SE
THAT YOU HAVE ALREADY SEEN?
>> CLEAR THERE SUN IMAGINABLE
TRAGEDY CONDOLENCES GO OUT
HOUSES OF WORSHIP.
PEOPLE WITH GRIEF ACROSS THEIR
FACES.
WE HAVE OVER 100 RED CROSS
WORKERS ON THE GROUND.
PROVIDING FOOD AND WATER.
MOST IMPORTANTLY EMOTIONAL
SUPPORT.
MENTAL HEALTH COUNSELING, NOT
ONLY TO THE FAMILIES AFFECTED
AND THE LARGER COMMUNITY BUT
TO THE FIRST RESPONDER WHO'S
HAVE BEEN SO PROFOUNDLY
AFFECTED?
>> Judge Jeanine: PEOPLE WHO
HAVEN'T SEEN THIS KIND OF
THING BEFORE.
I'M GOING TO GO TO YOU, BRAD,
NOW, YOU WERE HERE, HEY, GOOD
LUCK AND NOW YOU DECIDE, OH,
SITTING HERE QUIETLY WAITING
FOR HIS SHOT AND OF COURSE HE
JUST JUMPED DOWN.
SPARIKUS.
TELL US ABOUT HIM.
>> IS HE A 3-YEAR-OLD AKITA.
IS HE A CERTIFIED THERAPY DOG.
>> WHAT IS A THERAPY DOG.
WHAT DOES A THERAPY DOG DO.
>> PROVIDES COMFORT AND LOVE
TO THOSE WHO NEED HIM.
WE VOLUNTEER IN HOSPITAL
LOCALLY, SO WE VISIT WITH
CHILDREN AND PATIENTS HE SITS
THERE AND HANGS OUT WITH HIM.
PEOPLE WILL SIT THERE AND FEEL
COMFORTABLE.
DECOMPRESS WHAT'S GOING ON WHY
WORK TODAY AND LAST NIGHT WITH
CHILDREN AND THEIR FAMILIES.
WHEN COUNSELORS INVITE US IN.
BE WITH THE CHILD AND/OR
CHILDREN.
AND THE.
>> THEY ARE NOT AFRAID OF HIM
IN HE IS BIG AND BY THE WAY IS
HE BEAUTIFUL.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU CAN SEE
HIS EYES, HE WAS SITTING
QUIETLY FOR A FEW MINUTES.
IS HE A MAGNIFICENT DOG.
YOU ARE NOT WORRIED ABOUT A
CHILD UPSETTING HIM?
HE WON'T GET UPSET AND WON'T
BITE?
>> NO.
IS HE A VERY -- THERAPY DOGS
ONE OF THEIR QUALITIES ARE
THEY NEED TO LOVE CHILDREN.
BE GOOD AROUND ALL SORTS OF
ACTIVITY.
HE LOST CHILDREN BECAUSE OF
THE VOLUNTEER WORK DOING AT A
LOCAL HOSPITAL APPROPRIATE TO
COME UP AND BE WITH THE
CHILDREN TO HELP DECOMPRESS
FIRST RESPONDERS AND TEACHERS
AS WELL.
>> IS THIS NEW HAVING A DOG
COME IN.
I DON'T REMEMBER SEEING THIS
KIND OF THING USING A DOG AS
THERAPY.
>> NO MUCH.
IT'S WELL DOCUMENTED.
NOT WELL KNOWN MANY TIMES.
IN SPATICUS CASE FIRST TIME I
CONSIDERED MAKING HIM THERAPY
DOG 8 MONTHS OLD AND AUTISTIC
CHILD CAME UP TO US IN NEW
HAVEN GREEN.
8 YEARS OLD.
HE STAYED WITH US TWO AND A
HALF HOURS.
HE WAS VERY ARTICULATE.
WHEN HE LEFT US HE ASIDE FROM
THIS, THAT MAY BE ABLE TO GET
THEM PAST THE HUMP.
GETTING A DOG TO FOCUS ON FOR
THE CHILDREN WHO EITHER SAW
SOMETHING THAT HAPPENED IN
SCHOOL OR THE SIBLINGS OF
CHILDREN WHO HAVE BEEN LOST.
>> RED CROSS HAS STRESSED THE
IMPORTANCE OF PARENTS TALKING
TO THEIR KIDS, TALKING TO THEM
ABOUT THEIR FEARS TALKING
ABOUT THEIR SAFETY.
EVEN THE MOST SEASONED OF
VOLUNTEERS.
WE ARE HUMAN FIRST.
SO WE'RE HERE TAKING CARE OF
EACH OTHER COMING TOGETHER AS
A COMMUNITY.
MENTAL HEALTH COUNSELORS AND
PEOPLE CAN HELP YOU DEAL WITH
YOUR GRIEFS.
SO IMPORTANT.
>> Judge Jeanine: I WANT TO
THANK YOU DONNA MORSI AGAIN
ALL THAT YOU DO WITH THE RED
CROSS.
THANKS SO MUCH FOR BEING WITH
US.
OF COURSE, SPARTICUS -- HE IS
STARTING TO TURN AROUND.
ANYWAY, GOOD NIGHT, EVERYONE.
THANKS FOR BEING WITH US.
HOPEFULLY YOU JOIN US TOMORROW
NIGHT FOR ANOTHER SPECIAL
EDITION OF 9:00 OF JUSTICE.
THE INTERCOM IN THE OFFICE
WENT OFF AS IF THEY WERE GOING
IT MAKE ANNOUNCEMENT.
SCUFFLING NOISES.
I THOUGHT SOMEBODY HIT THE
BUTTON BY MISTAKE AND THEY
WERE IN THE OFFICE.
ONE OF THE SECRETARIES
ANSWERED THE PHONE AND SAID
THERE WAS A SHOOTING.
>> MAYHEM IN THE ROOM WITH ALL
THE KIDS AND TEACHERS TRYING
TO FIND YOUR KID.
IDENTIFY WHERE YOURS IS AND
MAKING SURE THEY ARE SAFE.
FIND OUT WHAT THE SITUATION
WAS.
>> SHE WAS IN A SMALL CLASS.
A READING GROUP AND THEY
STARTED HEARING, I GUESS,
BANGS.
AND HER TEACHER WHICH I'M SO
GRATEFUL FOR, THERE WAS JUST A
SMALL GROUP, THEY RUSHED THE
KIDS INTO THE BATHROOM, AND
THEY LOCKED THE DOOR.
AND THEY JUST TOLD THE
CHILDREN THAT IT WAS HAMMERING
AND TRIED TO KEEP THEM CALM.
THE NEXT THING I KNOW BECAUSE
IT'S VERY HARD TO GET THE
COMPLETE STORY.
THE NEXT THING I KNOW IS THAT
THE POLICE CAME IN AND THEY
WERE KNOCKING ON THE DOOR TO
BE LET OUT.
OF THE CLASSROOM.
AND WHEN THEY WERE, SHE HAD
SEEN GLASS AND BLOOD.
ONE CHILD WAS COVERED IN BLOOD
BUT I UNDERSTAND THAT CHILD IS
SAFE AND WAS NOT HURT AND MUST
HAVE BEEN SOMEBODY ELSE'S.
>> IT'S SHEAR TERROR AND A
SENSE OF IMMEDIATE URGENCY.
AND, YOU KNOW, TO GET TO YOUR
CHILD AND TO BE THERE TO
PROTECT THEM.
>> 18 CHILDREN PRONOUNCED DEAD
AT THE SCHOOL.
THERE WERE TWO THAT WERE
TRANSPORTED TO AREA HOSPITALS
AND PRONOUNCED DEAD AT AREA
HOSPITALS.
THERE WERE SIX ADULTS
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCENE
AT THE SCHOOL.
>> WE HAVE ENDURED TOO MANY OF
THESE TRAGEDIESED IN THE PAST
FEW YEARS.
AND EACH TIME I LEARN THE
NEWS, I REACT NOT AS A
PRESIDENT BUT AS ANYBODY ELSE
WOULD, AS A PARENT.
THAT WAS ESPECIALLY TRUE
TODAY.
I KNOW THERE IS NOT A PARENT
IN AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL
THE SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF
THAT I DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS
OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Sharable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
I'M GOING TO DREAM
ABOUT THAT STEAK.
ABOUT THAT TIRAMISU.
WHAT A NIGHT, HUH?
BUT, UM, CAN THE TEST DRIVE
BE OVER NOW?
HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A PASSAT.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN, $0 DUE AT SIGNING,
$0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
C'mon0manp
Just do it,quick.ú
No one's watchingp
You0have to if you
want to hang with0us
♪Musicú
The other one tooú
Good job