SCHOOL QUESTIONS HERE IN THE
COMMUNITY.
WE'LL BE IN CONTACT WITH THE
SUPERINTENDENT AND SOME
ADDITIONAL INFORMATION WE CAN
PROVIDE FOR YOU.
THANK YOU, GOOD AFTERNOON.
>> Rick: CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE, THE HEADLINE FOR THE
FIRST TIME THE POLICE HAVE NOW
IDENTIFIED 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM
LANZA AS THE SHOOTER.
THEY HAD NOT DONE THAT UP TO
THIS PRESS CONFERENCE.
THEY SAY HE WAS PRONOUNCED DEAD,
RULED HIS DEATH RULED A SUICIDE.
THEY ALSO FINISHED THE AUTOPSY
ON HIS MOTHER NANCY LANZA.
THE POLICE CONFIRMING THAT HE
SHOWED UP AT THE SCHOOL ON
FRIDAY AND THAT THE MAIN WEAPON
THAT HE USED TO CARRY OUT THIS
MASSACRE WAS A BUSHMASTER
ASSAULT TYPE WEAPON WITH
MULTIPLE HIGH CAPACITY
MAGAZINES.
HE FIRED OFF MANY BULLETS.
HE HAD HUNDREDS STILL ON HIM
THAT HE HADN'T YET FIRED OFF AT
THE TIME HE PULLED OUT ONE OF
PISTOLS THEAD AND KILLED HIMSELF
>> Heather: PRESIDENT SET TO
ATTEND A MEMORIAL SERVICE IN
NEWTOWN SHORTLY AFTER HIS
ARRIVAL BEFORE ADDRESSING THE
NATION IN WHAT WILL BE THE
FOURTH SPEECH THAT HE HAS HAD TO
MAKE FROM THE SITE OF A MASS
SHOOTING DURING HIS FIRST TERM
AS PRESIDENT.
NOW, WE'RE GOING TO GO TO CHIEF
WHITE HOUSE CORRESPONDENT, ED
HENRY WITH THE LATEST FROM
THERE.
>> Reporter: YOU ARE RIGHT.
YOU HEARD THE POLICE OFFICIALS
TALKING ABOUT THE INTENT,
SECURITY PRESENCE HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
RELATIVELY SMALL TOWN THAT HAS
HAD A HORRIBLE FEW DAYS HERE,
OBVIOUSLY THE PRESIDENT TRYING
TO HELP HEAL THE WOUNDS A BIT,
PERHAPS TONIGHT AT A PRAYER
VIGIL.
HE LEFT ANDREWS AIR FORCE BASE
AND BE ARRIVING BEHIND ME AT THE
HIGH SCHOOL SOON.
BOTTOM LINE HE WILL BE DOING A
SERIES OF THINGS.
ONE THING AS HE WILL BE MEETING
PRIVATELY WITH FAMILY MEMBERS OF
SOME OF THE VICTIMS.
SO MANY OF THEM SMALL CHILDREN.
YOU REMEMBER THE PRESIDENT ON
FRIDAY GREW EMOTIONAL IN THE
WHITE HOUSE BRIEFING ROOM,
CHOKING BACK TEARS, STOPPING AT
ONE POINT DURING HIS REMARKS AS
HE SPECIFICALLY TALKED ABOUT THE
YOUNG CHILDREN AFFECTED HERE.
AFTER MEETING WITH THE FAMILIES
HE WILL THANK FIRST RESPONDERS.
THEY HAVE BEEN ALL OVER ON THIS,
NOT JUST REACTING TO THE
HORRIFIC CRIME SCENE BUT ALSO
HELPING WITH COUNSELING, DEALING
WITH PEOPLE HERE ON THE GROUND
THAT ARE TRAUMATIZED.
A SPOKE WITH ONE GENTLEMAN THAT
NEW TWO PEOPLE THAT WERE KILLED,
ONE THAT PRINCIPAL THAT TRIED
AND ABLE TO AT LEAST SAVE OTHER
LIVES BY PUTTING HERSELF IN THE
LINE OF FIRE.
HE WAS AWARE CHILD THAT SURVIVED
WAS FORTUNATE TO LIVE THROUGH IT
AND STILL WAS TRAUMATIZED.
THAT FAMILY DEALING WITH THAT.
OBVIOUSLY HAS SPARKED A DEBATE
ABOUT GUN CONTROL, MAYOR MICHAEL
BLOOMBERG ON SOME OF THE TALK
SHOWS PRESSING OBAMA TO TAKE
ACTION.
YOU REMEMBER ON FRIDAY, IN HIS
REMARKS AT THE WHITE HOUSE,
PRESIDENT HINTED AT THAT SAYING
HE THINKS THERE SHOULD BE
MEANINGFUL ACTION THAT BOTH
PARTIES CAN COME TOGETHER IN THE
DAYS AHEAD.
I'M TOLD TO NOT EXPECT THE
PRESIDENT TO GUN CONTROL AT THE
HIGH SCHOOL HERE IN NEWTOWN.
HE BELIEVES IT'S NOT THE TIME
AND PLACE TO DO THAT.
TO FOCUS ON PRAYER AND
REMEMBRANCE.
NO DOUBT, WE'LL HEAR THE DEBATE
IN THE DAYS AHEAD.
>> Heather: THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> WELCOME TO A BRAND-NEW HOUR
OF AMERICA NEWS HEADQUARTERS AS
RICK SAID, I'M HEATHER CHILDERS.
>> Gregg: I'M GREGG JARRETT.
WE'LL FOLLOW THE MOVEMENTS OF
PRESIDENT AS HE VISITS TO FAMILY
MEMBERS AS WELL AS HIS REMARKS
BEFORE THE CONGREGATION.
>> IN THE PREPARATION AND
INVESTIGATION INTO THIS TRAGEDY
IS ACTUALLY GAINING SPEED.
AUTHORITIES SAY THE GUNMAN SHOT
HIS MOTHER, NOT ONCE BUT
MULTIPLE TIMES IN THE HEAD
BEFORE THEN GOING TO THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND COMMITTING
HIS FURTHER ATROCITIES.
MIKE TOBIN JOINS US LIVE.
THE LATEST DEVELOPMENTS IN THIS
CASE.
GIVE US A RUNDOWN.
>> Reporter: IT OFFERED A LOT OF
CLARITY ABOUT THE WEAPONS THAT
WERE USED IN THIS ATTACK.
PAUL VANCE, PUBLIC INFORMATION
FOR THE STATE POLICE SAYING
THERE WERE FOUR WEAPONS
INVOLVED.
PRIMARY WEAPON WAS BUSHMASTER
AR-15 ASSAULT RIFLE COUPLED WITH
HIGH CAPACITY MAGAZINES.
THAT WAS THE PRIMARY WEAPON USED
TO CARRY THROUGH THE ATTACK.
ALSO, A COUPLE OF SIDE ARMS.
.9 MILLIMETER AND GLOCK TEN
MILLIMETER.
ONE OF THOSE WERE USED BY THE
GUNMAN TO KILL HIMSELF AND WE
KNOW THAT HE KILLED HIMSELF AS
FIRST RESPONDERS WERE MOVING IN
ON THE SCENE.
SHOTGUN WAS LEFT OUT IN THE CAR.
ALL OF THESE WEAPONS WILL BE
VERY IMPORTANT THROUGHOUT THE
COURSE OF THIS INVESTIGATION.
>> WE ARE ANALYZING, EXAMINING
AND TRACE THEM BACK TO THEIR
ORIGIN.
WE WILL TRACE EVERY STEP OF THE
WAY AND WHERE THEY WERE USED AND
HOW THEY WERE USED.
A GREAT DEAL OF WORK MUST BE
DONE ON THOSE WEAPONS.
>> Reporter: WE ALSO LEARNED
FROM STATE POLICE THAT THE
AUTOPSIES WERE COMPLETED ON THE
LAST TWO BODIES REMOVED FROM THE
CRIME SCENE.
THOSE ARE THE BODIES OF THE
GUNMAN, ALSO NANCY LANZA, HIS
MOTHER.
THEY OFFER SOME CLARITY, SHE WAS
KILLED BY MULTIPLE GUNSHOT
WOUNDS TO THE HEAD.
A REPORT FROM ASSOCIATED PRESS
OFFERED MORE DETAIL SHE WAS
KILLED BY FOUR GUNSHOT WOUNDS TO
THE HEAD WHILE LAYING IN THE
BED.
THE GUNMAN IN A SUICIDE CASE WAS
KILLED BY A SINGLE SHOT TO THE
HEAD.
>> Gregg: WE'RE TOLD NOW THAT
THE PRESIDENT HAS ARRIVED IN
CONNECTICUT.
WHAT DO POLICE KNOW ABOUT THE
POSSIBLE MOTIVE HERE, THE EVER
ELUSIVE QUESTION OF WHY?
>> POLICE HAVE INDICATED THAT
THEY ARE, INDEED, GATHERING
EVIDENCE AND INFORMATION THAT
WILL ANSWER THE ONE QUESTION, OF
COURSE, THAT WE ALL WANT TO
KNOW.
WHY DID THIS HAPPEN?
AT THIS STAGE OF THE
INVESTIGATION THEY SAY THEY ARE
NOT GOING TO OFFER UP PARTIAL
INFORMATION.
>> WE HAVE TO HAVE THE WHOLE
PICTURE BEFORE WE CAN SAY
HOPEFULLY HOW AND WHY THIS
OCCURRED.
THAT IS NOT GOING TO COME VERY
QUICKLY.
>> Reporter: MEANTIME, FEDERAL
INVESTIGATORS HAVE FANNED OUT
ACROSS CONNECTICUT LOOKING INTO
GUN STORES AND GUN RANGES.
THEY ARE FOLLOWING UP TIPS AND
TRYING TO PUT TOGETHER A
TIMELINE OF WHAT LED TO THIS
HORRIFIC ATTACK.
>> Gregg: MIKE, THANK YOU.
TUNE IN TONIGHT BEGINNING AT
6:00 P.M. EASTERN TIME, FOR
COVERAGE OF PRESIDENT'S VISIT TO
NEWTOWN AND INTERFAITH VIGIL.
IT WILL BE HOSTED BY BRET BAIER,
WATCH IT HAPPEN LIVE RIGHT HERE
ON FOX.
>> Heather: POLICE DIFFUSE AGO
DANGEROUS SITUATION IN SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA.
ARRESTING A MAN THEY SAY FIRED
50 SHOTS INTO THE AIR AND INTO
THE GROUND AT A MALL PARKING
LOT.
STORES IN THE AREA WERE PUT ON
LOCKDOWN UNTIL THE SUSPECT WAS
TAKEN INTO CUSTODY.
FORTUNATELY NO ONE WAS INJURED.
>> Gregg: AN ALABAMA HOSPITAL IS
SECURE FOLLOWING A DEADLY
SHOOTING THERE.
INVESTIGATORS SAY A GUNMAN
SUDDENLY OPENED FIRE INSIDE THAT
FACILITY YESTERDAY HITTING A
POLICE OFFICER AS WELL AS TWO
HOSPITAL WORKERS.
SECOND OFFICER RETURNED FIRE AND
THEN KILLING THE SUSPECT.
HOSPITAL SAYS CARE FOR PATIENTS
IN THE VICINITY WAS NEVER
INTERRUPTED.
NO WORD YET ON A POSSIBLE
MOTIVE.
>> Heather: AS AUTHORITIES
CONTINUE THEIR INVESTIGATION IN
CONNECTICUT THERE IS A GROWING
FOCUS ON HOW THE FAMILIES OF THE
VICTIMS ARE SUPPOSED TO CONTINUE
THEIR LIVES AS USUAL AFTER THIS
HORRIFIC TRAGEDY.
THAT IS AN ONGOING STRUGGLE OF
ONE.
SHE IS WAS AMONG KILLED IN THE
MASS SHOOTING IN A COLORADO
MOVIE THEATER OVER THE SUMMER.
I KNOW ALL TOO WELL ABOUT THE
ROAD AHEAD FOR THE PEOPLES THAT
HAVE BEEN CHANGED FOREVER.
ANITA JOINS US BY PHONE.
SHE LOST HER CUNNING IN THAT
SHOOTING.
FIRST OF ALL, I IMAGINE WHEN ALL
OF THIS TRANSPIRED ON FRIDAY IT
IMMEDIATELY BROUGHT WHAT
HAPPENED JUST LAST SUMMER IN
AURORA BACK HOME TO YOU.
WHAT WERE YOUR FIRST THOUGHTS?
>> THE FAMILIES AND CRYING.
IT REALLY BACK THE TRAUMA OF THE
DAY.
>> Heather: WHAT ARE THESE
PARENTS, THESE FAMILIES, WHAT
ARE THEIR INITIAL RESPONSES.
WHAT DO YOU THINK THEIR FEELING
RIGHT NOW HAVING GONE THROUGH IT
YOURSELF?
>> TOTAL SHOCK.
OVERWHELMING GRIEF.
YOU QUESTION YOUR FAITH IN GOD.
ONE OF THE MOST IMPORTANT THINGS
I THINK FOR PEOPLE TO UNDERSTAND
THAT GOES THROUGH THIS IS THAT
GOD DID NOT TAKE THEM.
EVIL WANTS TO TAKE AWAY YOUR
FAITH IN GOD.
DON'T LET IT.
PEOPLE ARE QUESTIONING
EVERYTHING.
THEY EVENTUALLY ONCE THE SHOCK
WEARS OFF YOU REDEFINE YOUR LIFE
AND FUNCTION AGAIN.
MOST OF ALL PEOPLE WHO ARE
SUFFERING WANT TO FIND A WAY TO
HONOR THEIR LOVED ONES FOR THE
GREATER GOOD OF EVERYONE.
THAT IS WHAT THE AURORA SHOOTING
VICTIMS ARE DOING.
TO THAT END I WOULD REALLY
ENCOURAGE THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT TO PLEASE DON'T LET
WHAT HAPPENED TO THE VICTIMS OF
9/11 AND THE VICTIMS OF AURORA
HAPPEN TO THE VICTIMS OF SANDY
HOOK --.
>> Heather: WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
>> SOON AFTER NATIONAL TRAGEDY
LIKE THIS, ALL THESE FUNDS START
UP AND THEY COLLECT MONEY.
MOST IF NOT -- QUITE A FEW OF
THEM MONEY NEVER GETS DIRECTLY
TO THE VICTIMS.
WE WOULD ASK THAT THE GOVERNOR
OF CONNECTICUT LISTEN ESTABLISH
A VICTIMS COMPENSATION FUND.
YOU NEED HELP WITH TIME OFF WORK
TO GRIEVE, FUNERAL COSTS, PEOPLE
WANT TO GIVE IN AMERICA BUT THEY
ALSO WANT TO KNOW THAT THEIR
MONEY IS GOING DIRECTLY TO HELP
THE VICTIMS.
A VICTIMS COMPENSATION FUND IS
SET UP OR GIVE TO A NONPROFIT
AND MAKE SURE THAT THE MONEY
GOES DIRECTLY TO THE VICTIMS.
IT HAPPENED TO THE VICTIMS OF
9/11.
THEY HAD VERY WELL ESTABLISHED
NONPROFITS TAKING MONEY FROM THE
VICTIMS HAVE BEEN REPORTED ON
YOUR NETWORK AND OTHERS.
YOU HEARD THE BUREAU PRESIDENT
OF STATEN ISLAND AFTER SANDY,
STOP GIVING MONEY TO THE RED
CROSS BECAUSE WE'RE NOT SEEING
THE MONEY.
WE BEG THAT THE GOVERNOR HELP
THE VICTIMS WITH A TRUE PLAN TO
GET MONEY DIRECTLY TO THE
VICTIMS.
>> Heather: IN THESE INITIAL
MOMENTS, IT'S ONLY BEEN TWO DAYS
HOW LONG WILL IT TAKE FOR THESE
FAMILIES TO AT LEAST BEGIN TO
COME TO GRIPS WHAT HAPPENED.
AS YOU SAID, THEY ARE IN SHOCK.
HOW MANY DAYS DID IT TAKE YOU,
HOW MANY MONTHS?
>> WE'RE STILL GOING THROUGH IT.
IT DEPENDS ON THE PERSON.
WHAT HAPPENS WITH THIS IS YOU
HAVE HORRIFIC POST-TRAUMATIC
STRESS DISORDER IN VARYING
DEGREES.
THERE IS A WOMAN THAT CAN'T WORK
AND FUNCTION.
IT'S WHY MONEY THAT IS COLLECTED
GET TO THE VICTIMS.
ONE THING YOU HAPPENS, IT
OVERWHELMS YOU SO MUCH IT KEEPS
US FROM HEARING OUR OWN ANGELS.
IF YOU PAY ATTENTION, ANGELS
GIVE YOU SIGNS.
IF YOU PAY ATTENTION, WE HAVE
ALL IN AURORA WE HAVE SEEN SIGNS
BUT THE ARE SPIRITUAL SIGNS AND
SOMETIMES THE GRIEF OVERWHELMS
IT.
>> Heather: BEYOND THE MONEY AND
COMPENSATION THAT PEOPLE WILL
EVENTUALLY DONATE TO THESE
VICTIMS IN THIS HORRIFIC TRAGEDY
WHAT CAN PEOPLE THERE DO
IMMEDIATELY FOR THESE FAMILIES
TO TRY TO HELP HEAL THEM A
LITTLE QUICKER?
>> THE BEST THING THAT THE
FAMILIES CAN DO THEMSELVES, ITS
TIGHT-KNIT COMMUNITY, WHAT
HELPED US WE ALL GOT TOGETHER
AND HELPED US THROUGH IT.
WHEN YOU HAVE CHILDREN AND YOU
ARE DOING IN THE SAME SCHOOL
LIKE THAT, AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
A LOT OF THESE FAMILIES KNOW
EACH OTHER.
THEY SHOULD REACH OUT TO EACH
OTHER AND HELP EACH OTHER
THROUGH THIS.
THERE IS SO FEW PEOPLE THAT GO
THROUGH SOMETHING LIKE THIS ON A
NATIONAL SCALE.
THE MEDIA COMING DOWN ON YOU.
JUST PLEASE BE RESPECTFUL OF
THEIR PRIVACY, DON'T SHOW UP
THEIR HOUSE KNOCKING ON THE
WINDOWS OR DOORS.
PLEASE HAVE THE COMMUNITY
THEMSELVES PULL TOGETHER.
ALSO, MAYBE ESTABLISH ONE PERSON
WHO CAN CONTACT AND KEEP IN
TOUCH WITH ALL THE VICTIMS AND
SEE WHAT THEY NEED AND GO
THROUGH THAT PERSON SO THE
FAMILIES AREN'T CONSTANTLY BEING
BARRAGED.
>> Heather: THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR JOINING US.
WE HOPE THAT OTHERS IN THE
FUTURE WON'T HAVE TO ENDURE WHAT
YOU SAID.
>> Gregg: MEDICAL SCARE FOR DONE
TOP DIPLOMAT.
HILLARY CLINTON SUFFERING A FALL
AND CONCUSSION.
>> AND OFFERING PRAYERS FOR THE
VICTIMS FOR THE HORRIFIC
SHOOTING IN CONNECTICUT.
>> WE HEARD EVERYTHING, THE
SHOTS AND DOORS SLAMMING AND
PEOPLE YELLING.
HER HEART WAS RACING.
SHE WAS SCARED.
...so as you cans
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
>> Heather: AS THE PRESIDENT
PREPARES FOR HIS INTERFAITH
MEMORIAL TO REMEMBER THE VICTIMS
OF TRAGEDY SHOOTING, SUPPORT IS
BEEN POURING IN BY COMING
TOGETHER AT SUNDAY CHURCH
SERVICES AND DOING WHATEVER THEY
CAN TO HELP HEAL PEOPLE THEY
PROBABLY NEVER MET WHILE COMING
TO TERMS WITH EMOTIONS OF THEIR
OWN.
>> WE JUST GOT IN FROM
WASHINGTON, D.C. AND I SAY WHAT
WAS HAPPENING.
WE HAD TO GET BACK.
PRAY TO GOD TO HELP HEAL THESE
PEOPLE THAT LOST CHILDREN.
WE HAVE TWO DAUGHTERS.
I CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT IT MUST
FEEL LIKE.
>> PEOPLE WATCH THIS STUFF ON TV
AND COME AND SHOW YOUR SUPPORT.
LAY DOWN FLOWERS AND SHOW YOUR
SUPPORT.
>> IT'S AN UNIMAGINABLE LOSS.
THERE IS NOTHING YOU CAN SAY TO
CONSOLE THEM.
>> PEOPLE AT ONE NEWTOWN CHURCH,
THEY HAD A REPORTED BOMB THREAT
BUT POLICE GAVE THEM THE ALL
CLEAR SHORTLY AFTER THE CALL WAS
CALLED IN.
>> Gregg: NEW REPORTS SHOWING
SMALL BUSINESSES ARE FEELING THE
EFFECT IF DEMOCRATS AND
REPUBLICANS DON'T REEF AN
AGREEMENT SOON.
JOINING US IS BRENDA BUTTNER.
NEWLY SMAUL BUSINESSES THEY HAVE
TO BUDGET IN ADVANCE.
THEY HAVE TO BUDGET FOR THE
COMING QUARTER.
SO THEY ARE ALREADY TIGHTENING
THEIR BELT?
>> YOU BUDGET BASED ON WHAT THE
ECONOMY IS GOING TO DO OR WHAT
THE CUSTOMERS ARE GOING TO
SPEND.
WE HAD KEY SURVEYS THAT THE
OPTIMISM LEVEL OF SMALL BUSINESS
LEVELS IS AT RECORD LOWS CLOSE
TO WHAT IT WAS IN 2008 AND 2009
WHEN BASICALLY THE RECESSION
STARTED AND FINANCIAL MESS
IMPLODED.
50% OF SMALL BUSINESS OWNERS
THINK THAT THINGS ARE GOING TO
GET WORSE IN THE ECONOMY IN THE
NEXT SIX MONTHS.
IF YOU ARE DYING TO BUY THAT
COMPUTER OR HIRE THAT NEW PERSON
AND YOU THINK THINGS ARE GOING
TO GET WORSE, YOU REIN IN.
>> SMALL BUSINESSES CREATE 64%
OF NAY JOBS IN AMERICA.
THEY EMPLOY HALF OF THE WORKERS
IN UNITED STATES.
THE PRESIDENT IS HOLDING
ABSOLUTELY FIRM, I WANT TO RAISE
TAX RATES ON THOSE EARNING ABOVE
$250,000 A YEAR.
THAT IS 8 A 5% OF THE SMALL
BUSINESSES, ISN'T IT -- THAT IS
85% OF THE SMALL BUSINESSES,
ISN'T IT?
>> WHAT THEY DO IS FILE AS
INDIVIDUALS.
SO IF THE RATES ON INDIVIDUALS
ARE RAISED, NOT JUST ON PEOPLE
WHO MAKE $250,000 OR WHATEVER,
IT'S ON THE OWNERS.
A LOT OF THEM TAKE THEIR INCOME
AND FILE IT BACK INTO THE
BUSINESS IN ORDER TO GET BIGGER.
IF THEIR TAX RATES ARE GOING UP
IS GOING TO HAVE A CHILLING
EFFECT ON WHETHER THEY HIRE OR
SPEND.
THERE ARE OTHER ISSUES, 2% OF
PAYROLL TAX CUT WHICH HAS BEEN
IN EFFECT FOR TWO YEARS.
THAT IS GOING TO EFFECT A LOT OF
CUSTOMERS.
IT'S NOT JUST RICH PEOPLE.
IF YOU MAKE 40-60 K A YEAR YOU
ARE GOING TO LOSE $700 LESS THAT
YOU ARE GOING TO SPEND.
THEY SAY $95 BILLION BACK INTO
THE GOVERNMENT.
>> Gregg: THAT IS $95 BILLION
BACK INTO THE GOVERNMENT BUT
THAT MEANS $95 BILLION OUT OF
THE POCKETS OF CUSTOMERS TO
SPEND ON SMALL BUSINESSES?
>> THAT IS WHY IT'S NOT JUST A
TAX EFFECT ON SMALL BUSINESS
OWNERS BUT ON WHAT THEIR
CUSTOMERS ARE GOING TO DO.
WE'RE ALREADY SEEING A CUT BACK
BY OWNERS IN TERMS OF BUYING NEW
SOFTWARE OR EQUIPMENT SPENDING.
THERE HAS BEEN A DECLINE.
SO THAT IS NOW.
WITH THIS UNCERTAINTY MOVING
FORWARD YOU CAN ONLY EXPECT THEY
WOULD PULL BACK.
>> Gregg: MOST OF JOB CREATION
HAS COME FROM SMALL BUSINESSES.
DO YOU SEE THAT REVERSING ITSELF
IF THE PRESIDENT MAINTAINS HIS
POSITION ON TAXING THOSE MAKING
MORE THAN $250,000 A YEAR?
>> THE ISSUE IS THEY CREATE A --
THEY ARE BASICALLY THE ENGINE OF
JOB CREATION.
THEY EMPLOY ABOUT HALF OF THE
AMERICANS EMPLOYED RIGHT NOW.
WILL IT HAVE AN IMPACT ON
EMPLOYMENT RATE?
I THINK IT HAS TO.
>> Gregg: EXPERTS SAY IF WE GO
OVER THE FISCAL CLIFF THERE WILL
BE RECESSION.
DO SMALL BUSINESSES HAVE THE
MOST TO LOSE?
>> THEY LIVE MONTH TO MONTH MUCH
MORE SO THAN HUGE CORPORATIONS
AND HAVE OTHER THINGS THEY CAN
RELY ON.
>> Gregg: THEY HAVE BRIDGE LOANS
TO GET THROUGH THEM PAYROLL TO
GET THEM THROUGH THE MONTH AND
THAT WILL GO AWAY.
>> THAT IS THE FEAR.
>> Gregg: SINCE SMALL BUSINESSES
MAKE UP 54% OF EMPLOYING
AMERICANS THAT WILL BE A HUGE
IMPACT.
>> Heather: CATCH BRENDA BUTTNER
ON "BULLS AND BEARS", HERE ALL
THE TIME.
THANK YOU BRENDA.
THE CONNECTICUT SCHOOL TRAGEDY
WE'RE GOING TO TALK ALLEGE MORE
ABOUT THAT.
SCHOOL SAFETY, EVERYONE IS
TALKING ABOUT THAT.
BACK INTO THE NATIONAL SPOTLIGHT
A LOOK WHAT NEEDS TO BE DONE TO
MAKE SURE THAT OUR ARE SAFE.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
SOMETHING MADE YOUR JAW DROP?
CAMPBELL'S HAS 24 NEW SOUPS
THAT WILL MAKE IT DROP OVER,
AND OVER AGAIN.
♪
FROM JAMMIN' JERK CHICKEN,
TO CREAMY GOUDA BISQUE.
SEE WHAT'S NEW FROM CAMPBELL'S.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
IS EFFICIENTLY ABSORBED IN SMALL
CONTINUOUS AMOUNTS.
Citracal Slow Release
CONTINUOUSLY RELEASES CALCIUM
PLUS D
WITH EFFICIENT ABSORPTION
IN ONE DAILY DOSE.
Citracal Slow Release.
WI HAD[ Designer ]EELINGN
ENOUGH OF JUST COVERING UP
MY MODERATE TO SEVERE
PLAQUE PSORIASIS.
I DECIDED ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
♪
[ Spa Lady ]
I STARTED ENBREL.
IT'S CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO PROVIDE CLEARER SKIN.
[ RV Guy ] ENBREL MAY NOT WORK
FOR EVERYONE --
AND MAY NOT CLEAR YOU
COMPLETELY,
BUT FOR MANY, IT GETS SKIN
CLEARER FAST, WITHIN 2 MONTHS,
AND KEEPS IT CLEARER
UP TO 9 MONTHS.
[ Male Announcer ]
BECAUSE ENBREL®, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL,
EVENTS INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS, LYMPHOMA,
OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING ENBREL,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START ENBREL IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON ENBREL, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING,
OR PALENESS.
IF YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH, ASK
YOUR DERMATOLOGIST ABOUT ENBREL.
>>.
>> Heather: WELCOME BACK.
TIME FOR A CHECK ON THE OTHER
STORIES.
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON IS RECOVERING AT HOME
AFTER SUFFERING A CONCUSSION
AFTER FAINTING.
DOCTORS ARE ADVISING HER TO REST
AND CANCEL ALL WORK EVENTS THE
NEXT WEEK.
THE DEATH TOLL FROM A TYPHOON IS
NOW OVER 1,000 AND IT COULD
STILL RISE SHARPLY.
OVER 800 STILL MISSING.
IN SPAIN, MORE THAN 5,000
MEDICAL WORKERS TAKING TO THE
STREETS PROTESTING BUDGET CUTS
AND TO PARTLY PRIVATIZE THE
COUNTRY'S HEALTH SERVICE.
>> Gregg: AS THE TRAGIC SHOOTING
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT INSPIRES
SOUL SEARCHING NATIONWIDE,
EVERYTHING FROM SCHOOL SAFETY TO
MENTAL ILLNESS TO THE FAMILY
ITSELF, THERE IS GROWING DEBATE
OVER JUST HOW LAWMAKERS ARE
REACTING.
WHAT KIND OF DIALOGUE THIS
HORRIFYING CRIME MIGHT INSPIRE
IN OUR NATION'S CAPITAL.
STEVE CENTANNI HAS MORE ON THAT.
>> Reporter: SHOCK AND SADNESS
IN WASHINGTON, THAT FOR SURE IN
THE WAKE OF THAT TRAGEDY IN
NEWTOWN AND AT THE SAME TIME
SOME IDEAS ARE BEING FLOATED
AIMED AT PREVENTING THE SAME
KIND OF THING FROM HAPPENING
AGAIN.
OUT GOING SENATOR JOE LIEBERMAN
AND INDEPENDENT FROM CONNECTICUT
HAS THIS RECOMMENDATION.
>> I THINK WE NEED A NATIONAL
COMMISSION ON MASS VIOLENCE, NOT
TO BE IN PLACE 6 ANYTHING ELSE
THE PRESIDENT OR CONGRESS OR
STATE GOVERNMENTS MIGHT WANT TO
DO BUT TO MAKE SURE THAT THE
HEARTBREAK AND THE ANGER THAT WE
FEEL NOW IS NOT DISSIPATED OVER
TIME OR LOST IN LEGISLATIVE
GRIDLOCK.
>> Reporter: IN HIS CALL FOR A
NATIONAL COMMISSION.
THE SENATOR IS SUPPORTED BY
DEMOCRATIC SENATOR DICK DURBIN
OF ILLINOIS.
ALSO ON THE TALK SHOWS, JASON A
REPUBLICAN OF UTAH SAYS THAT WE
NEED TO EXPLORE WHAT HE CALLS
THE INTERSECTION OF LETHAL
WEAPONS AND MENTAL HEALTH.
HE SAYS VIOLENCE AND MEDIA ARE
MAJOR FACTORS IN THE EQUATION.
>> WE ALSO HAVE TO DEAL WITH THE
NEW SOCIAL RAMIFICATIONS OF THE
BOMBARDMENT AND SOCIAL
INTERACTION BETWEEN VIOLENCE,
THE REALISM THAT YOU FIND AT
GAMES AND MOVIES.
SOME PEOPLE, YOUNG PEOPLE ARE
MAKING THIS TRANSITION FROM TEEN
YEARS INTO ADULT HOOD AREN'T
TABLE TO MAKE THAT TRANSITION.
THERE DOES NEAT TO BE HELP.
WE NEED TO LOOK AT FAMILIES AND
COMMUNITIES AND CHURCHES.
IT'S NOT JUST A GOVERNMENT
SOLUTION.
>> Reporter: AND HOMELAND
SECURITY SECRETARY TOM RIDGE
SAYING THE PROBLEM LIES WITH
APPROXIMATE OF MENTAL HEALTH AND
DESTRUCTIVE BEHAVIOR.
>> Gregg: STEVE LIVE IN
WASHINGTON, THANK YOU.
AS THE PRESIDENT PREPARES TO
SPEAK TO HEARTBROKEN FAMILIES TO
THE VICTIMS OF NEWTOWN TONIGHT,
THERE IS A GROWING DEBATE OVER
WHAT KIND OF MESSAGE AMERICA
NEEDS TO HEAR FROM OUR COMMANDER
IN CHIEF.
WHETHER IT WILL MATCH UP WITH
HIS REMARKS TONIGHT.
WE'LL PUT POLITICS ASIDE AND
TALK WITH OUR PANEL.
>> Heather: THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL TRAGEDY RENEWING CALLS
FOR STRONGER SECURITY MEASURES
AT SCHOOLS.
AS PARENTS ALL ACROSS THE
COUNTRY PREPARE TO TAKE THEIR
CHILDREN BACK TO SCHOOL TOMORROW
MORNING.
WHAT MORE CAN BE DONE TO MAKE
SURE OUR SCHOOLS ARE SAFE.
DOMINIC HAS MORE ON THIS.
>> THE MEASURES TO KEEP SCHOOLS
SAFE HAVE BEEN LONG ESTABLISHED.
SECURITY EXPERTS SAY WHAT IS
NEEDED IS GREATER IMPLEMENTATION
BY SCHOOLS AND BETTER
COORDINATION WITH AUTHORITIES.
THEY SAY THAT IS REALLY NOT VERY
HARD TO DO.
>> WE DON'T NEED TO BE TEACHING
KINDERGARTENERS TO THROW BOOK
BAGS AND PENCILS AT ARMED
INTRUDERS OR METAL DETECTOR AT
EACH DOOR.
WE NEED TO FOCUS ON FUNDAMENTALS
HAVING LOCK DOWN DRILLS AND
WORKING COOPERATEDIVELY WITH
POLICE THAT TAKE MORE TIME THAN
THEY DO MONEY.
>> Reporter: THERE HAS BEEN A
NUMBER OF CUTS IN SECURITY
BUDGETS IN FEDERAL AND LOCAL
LEVELS.
EXPERTS SAY WE MAY NEED MORE
MONEY FOR TWO-RAY RADIOS OR
EXTRA COUNSELORS MANY MEASURES
DO NOT REQUIRE MONEY, THEY
REQUIRE TIME TO MAKE SURE THAT
PEOPLE ARE PREPARED.
GOOD EXAMPLE WOULD BE THAT MANY
SCHOOLS AND ADMINISTRATORS CAN
ORDER A LOCKDOWN.
THAT SHOULD CHANGE.
>> THAT IS UNACCEPTABLE.
IF YOU ARE IN A SCHOOL WHERE
ONLY ADMINISTRATORS ARE ALLOWED
TO DO A LOCKDOWN.
WE NEED TO HAVE TRAINING TO
EMPOWER YOU AND TRAIN YOU ON HOW
TO DO ONE YOURSELF.
ANY ADULT IN THAT BUILDING THAT
SEES A DANGEROUS SITUATION
SHOULD BE ABLE TO CARRY OUT A
LIFE SAVING FUNCTION.
>> Reporter: AND ADULTS LIKE THE
JANITOR OR NON-TEACHER.
ALL THE EXPERTS WE TALK TO ABOUT
SAFETY, PREVENTION AND CRISIS
PLANNING IS ALL PART OF THE
TRAINING AGENDA.
THEY WANT EVERYBODY TRAINED THAT
WORKS IN A SCHOOL.
OF COURSE, BRING IN PARENTS AS
WELL SO THEY UNDERSTAND WHAT
SHOULD HAPPEN IN THE EVENT OF AN
ATTACK LIKE WE SAW IN
CONNECTICUT.
>> Heather: THAT MAKES SENSE.
THANK YOU DOMINIC.
>> Gregg: WHILE THE NATION WAS
FOCUSED ON THE TRAGIC EVENTS IN
CONNECTICUT.
POLICE AND SCHOOL OFFICIALS IN
OKLAHOMA WERE DISRUPTED AGO
SCHOOL SHOOTING PLOT OF THEIR
OWN.
18-YEAR-OLD IS BEHIND BARS RIGHT
NOW ACCUSED OF PLOTTING AND BOMB
TO SHOOT STUDENTS IN THE
AUDITORIUM OF A HIGH SCHOOL
NORTH OF TULSA.
FORTUNATELY FELLOW STUDENTS HELP
PREVENT A TRAGEDY.
>> THE PROCESS WE HAD WE NEED
PLACE WORKED REALLY WELL.
WHAT WE HAVE IN PLACE, WE'RE
GOING TO CONTINUE TO USE THAT.
HOPEFULLY WE NEVER HAVE TO DEAL
WITH THIS A SITUATION LIKE THIS
AGAIN.
ANY TIME WE ARE CONCERNED ABOUT
THE SAFETY OF OUR STUDENTS, THAT
IS OUR PRIORITY.
>> Gregg: SCHOOL OFFICIALS THEY
ARE ADDING EXTRA PATROLS TO KEEP
PEOPLE SAFE FOR THE NEXT FEW
WEEKS.
>> Heather: REBELS IN SYRIA HAVE
CAPTURED A MILITARY WAYS.
THAT REPORT COMING AS THE FRENCH
FOREIGN MINISTER PREDICTS THE
END IS NEARING FOR PRESIDENT
ASSAD.
THE NEW COALITION OF OPPOSITION
LEADERS WOULD HAVE TO BE
SUPPORTED IN THE EVENT THAT THE
ASSAD REGIME IS TOPPLED TO
PREVENT EXTREMISTS TO BE ABLE TO
TAKE CONTROL.
>> Gregg: ALSO NOW IN THE MIDDLE
EAST, SLUAYIST LEADERS IN EGYPT
CLAIM THEY HAVE A MAJORITY OF
VOTES IN THE FIRST ROUND OF
REFERENDUM IN A DRAFT
CONSTITUTION BUT ALLEGATIONS OF
WIDESPREAD FRAUD ARE CASTING A
SHADOW OVER THAT VOTE SETTING
THE STAGE FOR POSSIBLY MORE
VIOLENT PROTESTS.
GREG PALKOT IS STREAMING LIVE
FROM CAIRO, EGYPT WITH MORE.
>> THOSE IN FAVOR OF THIS
CONTROVERSIAL CONSTITUTION WILL
6 THEIR WAY THE ELECTION IS THE
FIRST OF TWO ROUND.
WE'RE GETTING PRELIMINARY
RESULTS IN CAIRO AND ELSEWHERE,
BUT WHAT WE'RE SEEING IS THE YES
VOTED, 57%, THE NO VOTE IS 43.
THE TURN OFF WAS DOWN BY
EGYPTIAN STANDARDS AND THEY ARE
REPORTING WIDESPREAD
IRREGULARITIES BUT THE
GOVERNMENT SEEMS TO BE
DISMISSING THOSE CHARGES.
IT WAS MARRED BY THE VIOLENCE WE
HAVE SEEN HERE IN JIT FOR THE
LAST COUPLE OF WEEKS.
THE HEADQUARTERS OF A POLITICAL
PARTY ATTACKED BY THE ISLAMISTS,
THIS IS SOMETHING LIKE 120,000
EGYPTIAN SOLDIERS MOBILIZED FOR
THE DAY.
IF THE PRO CONSTITUTION IS
FAVORED BY MORSI DEFENDERS ARE
SAYING THAT IT IS NEEDED TO
PROTECT THE GAINS OF THE
REVOLUTION.
NEXT SATURDAY SECOND AND FINAL
ROUND OF VOTING WILL BE IN RURAL
AREAS.
THESE AREAS ARE FRIENDLY TO THE
CONSERVATIVE ISLAMISTS.
SO IT SEEMS THAT THE
CONSTITUTION WILL GO THROUGH.
THERE IS A CANS THAT MODIFY IT
AFTER THE FACT.
THERE ARE ELECTIONS CALLED FOR A
NEW PARLIAMENT BUT AGAIN IT
APPEARS THAT THE ISLAMISTS WILL
REMAIN IN CHARGE.
AS YOU NOTED THAT COULD MEAN THE
THREAT OF VIOLENCE REMAINS AS
WELL AND THE CHALLENGE OF
RUNNING THIS COUNTRY.
>> Gregg: JUST SHY OF MIDNIGHT,
GREG PALKOT LIVE IN CAIRO,
EGYPT.
THANKS.
>> Heather: STILL TO COME, CALLS
FOR ACTION GROWING LOUD THEY ARE
THE WAKE OF CONNECTICUT
SHOOTING.
OUR LEGAL PANEL WEIGHS IN WHAT
IF ANYTHING THE JUSTICE SYSTEM
CAN DO TO PREVENT TRAGEDIES LIKE
THE ONE IN NEWTOWN.
THE BOYS USE
Capital One Venture Miles
FOR THEIR ANNUAL FOOTBALL TRIP.
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE.
TRAGICALLY, THEIR DDY
GOT SACKED BY BLACKOUTS.
BUT IT'S OUR TRADITION!
THAT'S ROUGHING
THE CARD HOLDER.
BUT WITH
THE Capital One Venture Card
YOU GET DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE.
[ cheering ]
ANY FLIGHT, ANYTIME.
THE SCOREBOARD DOESN'T LIE.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET? HUT!
I HAVE ME ON MY FANTASY TEAM.
Neural speeds
increasing to 4G LTE.
Brain upgrading to a quad-core
processor.
Predictive intelligence
with Google Now complete.
Introducing DROID DNA by HTC.
It's not an upgrade
to your phone.
It's an upgrade to yourself.
>>.
>> Gregg: THE SCALE OF HORROR IN
CONNECTICUT IS UNIMAGINABLE.
NOW GROWING CALLS FOR ACTION TO
PREVENT THIS FROM HAPPENING
AGAIN IF THAT IS EVEN POSSIBLE.
THE S THERE ANYTHING THE
CRIMINAL JUSTICE SYSTEM CAN
LEARN FROM THIS TRAGEDY.
LET'S BRING IN OUR LEGAL PANEL.
LOOK WE ADMIT WE DON'T HAVE ALL
THE FACTS AND WE DON'T KNOW ALL
THE MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES.
HAVING SAID ALL OF THAT, FROM A
LEGAL STANDPOINT, YOU THINK
THERE CAN BE SOMETHING DONE IN
THE MENTAL HEALTH FIELD?
>> I REALLY DO.
ALL OF US HAVE BEEN SHAKEN TO
CORE.
THIS IS TRAGIC.
WE TURN OUR ATTENTION TO
LOGISTICALLY.
WHERE MENTAL HEALTH OFFICIALS
HAVE A DUTY TO WARN, WHEN THEY
ARE TREATING THE MENTALLY ILL
WHETHER YOU ARE PSYCHOLOGIST OR
PSYCHIATRIST BUT IF LAWS CAN BE
STRENGTHENED THAT IT DOESN'T
REQUIRE AN IMMINENT THREAT UPON
THE PUBLIC BUT A MEASURE OF
THREAT THAT IS DETECTED UPON
TREATING THE MENTALLY ILL AND
THEY REPORT THAT, PERHAPS IT
COULD RESULT IN PREVENTION.
THAT THE FIRST STEP.
WE LOOK AT SCHOOLS AT OUR
SANCTUARY AND WHEN THINGS HAPPEN
IN SCHOOLS, WHEN WE GO TO WORK
IN A PEACEFUL WAY BECAUSE WE
KNOW OUR CHILDREN ARE SAFE.
WHEN YOU INVADE THAT, THERE IS A
PROBLEM.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> Gregg: NANCY LANZA COLLECTED
GUNS, APPARENTLY SHE WENT SO FAR
TO TAKE HER SON TO FIRING RANGES
TO TEACH HIM HOW TO USE THEM.
THEY PRACTICED QUITE OFTEN.
AN AUTISM EXPERT SAID VIOLENT
TENDENCIES ARE NOT COMMON
ASSOCIATED WITH ASPERGER'S BUT
ANY CHILD WITH A NEUROLOGICAL OR
PSYCHOLOGICAL DISORDER SHOULD
NOT LIVE FROM A HOUSE WITH
ACCESS TO GUNS.
>> OBVIOUSLY, WE'RE ALL SICKENED
BUT HERE A PARENT THAT HAS A
CHILD SPECIAL NEEDS.
WE DON'T KNOW IF THIS CHILD
GROWING UP HAD ANY SORT OF
MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES.
OBVIOUSLY THEY KNOW ABOUT IT BUT
WE DON'T KNOW IF HE WAS TREATED.
THERE WERE SIGNS HE HAD SOME
ILLNESS.
HE WITH A PULLED IN AND OUT OF
SCHOOL, HOME SCHOOL FOR A PERIOD
OF TIME.
THEN DON'T BRING GUNS.
I KNOW THAT GUNS WERE BOUGHT
LEGALLY AND REGISTERED BUT DON'T
HAVE ACCESS TO GUNS THAT HAVE
SPECIAL NEEDS.
>> Gregg: CAN WE STRENGTHEN
CIVIL COMMITMENT, AS WELL?
>> I THINK WE CAN.
THERE ARE CIVIL CONFINEMENT LAWS
AND THOSE REQUIRE AN ALLOW
MENTAL HEALTH PROFESSIONALS TO
COMMIT PEOPLE AGAINST THEIR
WILL.
I'M NOT SUGGESTING THAT AT ANY
HINT OF MENTAL ILLNESS WE HAD
YOU HAD SHOULD PULL THEM OFF THE
STREET.
WE HAVE TO TAKE A CLOSER LOOK,
BUT WE HAVE TO TAKE A CLOSER
LOOK AND IF THERE IS SOMETHING
AMISS AND RECOMMENDED BY
PSYCHOLOGISTS THEY BE COMMITTED,
I THINK IT'S TIME TO DO SO.
>> EVERY JURISDICTION HAVE A
MENTAL HEALTH LAW THAT PERMITS
INVOLUNTARY COMMITMENT UP TO 30
DAYS.
EXACTLY, BUT AT LEAST THEY CAN
DO DIAGNOSIS PARTICULARS TO
DETERMINE IF THEY POSE A THREAT.
>> Gregg: WHAT ABOUT A GREATER
MONITORING OF SOME OF THESE HIGH
RISK VENUES, WHETHER MOVIE
THEATERS OR SCHOOLS.
>> IT'S HARD BECAUSE NO ONE IS
IMMUNE.
IF YOU LOOK K-4, YOU HAD A
UNIVERSITY SHOOTING AT VIRGINIA
TECH, LOOK OUTSIDE A GROCERY
STORE, WHERE DOES IT STOP?
AS A RESULT OF THOSE SHOOTINGS
THERE NEED TO BE COLLECTIVE
EFFORT, LEGISLATION WOULD BE
HELPFUL IN THIS REGARD TO GET
LAW ENFORCEMENT TO HAVE A GREAT
PRESENCE IN THOSE AREAS.
>> Gregg:LY SAY THIS -- IT SEEMS
LAW ENFORCEMENT RESPONDED
IMMEDIATELY.
SECOND OF ALL THIS SCHOOL DID
HAVE ITS OWN LOCKDOWN SYSTEM.
THEY HAD PRACTICED DRILLS.
I WANT TO COMPLIMENT THE SCHOOL.
GREATER NUMBER OF LIVES COULD
HAVE BEEN LOST.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
WE KNOW THE SHOOTER BROKE INTO
THE SCHOOL.
THEY HAD THE LOCKDOWN SYSTEM IN
PLACE AND THERE WAS OBVIOUSLY
SECURITY.
>> Gregg: THERE IS THIS
PHENOMENON, CALL THE BLACK SWAN,
METAPHOR USED, STATISTICAL TERM
USED TO DESCRIBE AN ANOMALY THAT
IS SO INCREDIBLY RARE IT CAN'T
BE ANTICIPATED.
I DEVOTED YESTERDAY A DOCTOR AT
THE UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS, IT'S
ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE WHO IS GOING
TO BE THE NEXT ONE TO CARRY OUT
TO DETECT THAT PERSON.
>> THAT IS WHAT TO TAKE IT
FURTHER, YOU NEVER KNOW WHEN,
WHERE, HOW OR WHAT, IT SEEMS
LIKE WE CAN'T LET IT.
>> IF LAW ENFORCEMENT AND SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGISTS, THEY HAVE THAT
DUTY TO COME FORWARD AND SAY
THIS PERSON MAY POSE A THREAT
WHETHER IN THE WORKPLACE, THE
SCHOOLS, AT LARGE.
WE NEED TO DO SOMETHING ABOUT
IT.
>> TO MAKE IT MORE PROBABLE TO
PREVENT SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
>> Gregg: I WANT TO END THIS BY
SAYING THERE ARE TENS OF
THOUSANDS OF SCHOOLS THAT ARE
COMPLETELY SAFE.
WE DON'T WANT TO FRIGHTEN THE
CHILDREN.
THAT IS THE MESSAGE THAT ALL OF
US WANT TO MAKE.
>>> GREAT POINT.
>> Gregg: JOEY JACKSON AND
MERCEDES, THANK YOU.
>> Heather: AS THE PRESIDENT
PREPARES TO SPEAK WITH THE
HEARTBROKEN FAMILIES IN NEWTOWN
TONIGHT, THERE IS GROWING DEBATE
OVER WHAT KIND OF MESSAGE
AMERICA NEEDS TO HEAR FROM OUR
COMMANDER IN CHIEF.
WHETHER IT WILL MATCH UP WITH
HIS REMARKS TONIGHT.
WE PUT POLITICS ASIDE AND
DISCUSS THAT WITH THE PANEL FAIR
AND BALANCED, SO STAY TUNED.
[ Male Announcer ]
RED LOBSTER'S CRABFEST
ENDS SOON.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OURENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
>>.
>> Heather: PRESIDENT OBAMA'S
VISIT TO THE TRAGIC MASS
SHOOTING MARKS THE FOURTH TIME
HE HAS VISITED THE SCENE OF SUCH
A CRIME RIGHT HERE ON U.S. SOIL.
WITH JUST OVER TWO HOURS UNTIL
HE ADDRESSES THE NATION TO THE
DEVASTATED FAMILIES, MANY PEOPLE
ARE WONDERING WHAT WILL THE
PRESIDENT SAY?
WHETHER IT WILL MATCH UP WITH
WHAT AMERICANS NEED TO HEAR AND
EXACTLY WHAT THAT MIGHT BE.
JOINING ME IS TALK RADIO NEWS
SERVICE, ELLEN RATNER AND MIKE
SLATER.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
I'LL TOSS IT TO BOTH OF YOU.
WHAT DO YOU EXPECT THE PRESIDENT
WILL SAY THIS EVENING?
>> I'M NOT SURE WHAT TO EXPECT.
I THINK WE NEED TO HEAR A
MESSAGE OF LOVE.
IT CAN START WITH OUR FAMILIES.
THERE ARE 20 HOMES IN
CONNECTICUT WITH EMPTY BEDS AND
LONELY TOYS AND WRAPPED
PRESENTS.
THERE ARE 20 GRIEVING FAMILIES
THAT WANT MORE THAN ANYTHING TO
SEE THEIR KIDS FOR ONE MORE HUG
AND SHOWER THEM WITH MORE LOVE.
I THINK THE MESSAGE OF
ENCOURAGING MORE ACTIVE AND
ENGAGED PARENTS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY.
THAT IS THE MESSAGE WE NEED TO
HEAR THAT ALL THE TIME.
>> Heather: THEY'LL BE TWO
GROUPS OF PEOPLE HE WILL BE
SPEAKING TO, PRIVATELY HE WILL
SPEAK TO THE VICTIMS AND
FAMILIES BUT WHEN THEY LISTEN TO
HIM WHEN HE SPEAKS TO THE
COUNTRY THEY WILL BE LISTENING
TO SOMETHING, THE REST OF US
WILL BE LISTENING TO SOMETHING.
WHAT DOES HE NEED TO DO?
>> IN M RESPECTS HE SHOULDN'T
EVEN SPEAK.
I THINK HE SHOULD BE THERE AND
NOT NECESSARILY TALK.
IT'S TRUE THAT THE REST OF THE
COUNTRY IS WAITING FOR HIM TO
TALK.
OBVIOUSLY HIS EXPERIENCE AS A
PARENT IS VERY IMPORTANT.
JUST LIKE YOU SAID, THE ISSUE OF
ONE LAST HUG, BUT ALSO HE MADE A
SPEECH ON 9/11 THAT I THOUGHT
WAS AMAZING ON TENTH
ANNIVERSARY.
HE SAID IT IS WORTH REMEMBERING
WHAT HASN'T CHANGED, OUR
CHARACTER AS A NATION AND FAITH
IN GOD HASN'T CHANGED.
WITH GOD AS OUR GUIDE LET'S
HONOR THOSE THAT HAVE BEEN LOST
AND LET'S LOOK TO THE FUTURE
WITH HEARTS OF HOPE.
IF HE SAYS SOMETHING ALONG THOSE
LINES THAT WILL BE VERY
POIGNANT.
>> Heather: HE CAME OUT ON
FRIDAY AND HIS FIRST COMMENT, HE
SHED A FEW TEARS, DO YOU EXPECT
TO SEE THAT TYPE OF EMOTION FROM
HIM SPEAKING NOT JUST AS A
PRESIDENT BUT ALSO AS FATHER
THIS TIME AROUND?
>> I HOPE SO.
I HOPE HE CONNECTS AS A DAD
FIRST AND POLITICS NEVER.
THE IDEA THERE IS NO SUCH THING
AS DARKNESS, WE CALL THE ABSENCE
OF LIGHT.
I'M INSPIRED BY ONE OF TEACHERS
PUT ALL THE KIDS IN THE
CLASSROOM AND TELLING THEM, I
LOVE YOU ALL SO MUCH.
HE DIDN'T WANT THE LAST THING
FOR THEM TO HEAR IS GUNFIRE.
SO IN THE FACE OF THIS DARKNESS,
SHE WANTED TO PROVIDE A RAY OF
LIGHT AND TO PROVIDE COMFORT AND
HOPE FOR THESE KIDS.
SHE WAS ABLE TO DO THAT.
I SAY THAT BECAUSE WE ALL HAVE
THE OPPORTUNITY TO BE A RAY OF
LIGHT TO SOMEONE.
EVERYONE IS DEALING WITH SOME
DARKNESS OR LONELINESS OR SOME
DOUBT.
WE HAVE THE OPPORTUNITY TO BE AN
ELEMENT OF KINDNESS AND
ENCOURAGEMENT TO PEOPLE.
LET'S NOT FORGET WE ALL HAVE THE
OPPORTUNITY TO DO THAT WITH THE
PEOPLE IN OUR CIRCLE AS WELL.
>> Heather: I HEARD THIS TOSSED
AROUND A LOT, A DESCRIPTION OF
NOT BEING THE COMMANDER IN CHIEF
BUT TAKING THE ROLL ON AS THE
COMFORTER IN CHIEF.
DO YOU THINK THAT SHOULD BE THE
FIRST PRIORITY?
>> HE HAS DONE THAT.
THAT IS WHY I SAID I'M NOT SURE
WORDS ARE IMPORTANT OR HE SHOULD
EVEN SPEAK.
PEOPLE WANT TO SEE THE PRESIDENT
IS THERE AND HE CAN REACH OUT TO
PEOPLE AND COMFORT THEM AND BE
THERE.
HE LISTENS TO THEM THAT HE HEARS
THEM, THAT IS WHAT I THINK WE
WANTED TO SEE FOR OURSELVES.
>> Heather: WHAT ABOUT LESSONS
HE CAN SHARE FROM THIS TRAGEDY
AND SINCE HIS TIME IN THE OVAL
OFFICE?
>> I THINK THAT IS VERY
DIFFICULT.
I'M NOT SURE THAT THOSE KINDS OF
LESSONS.
HE IS NOT A PREACHER, HE IS THE
PRESIDENT FOR HIM TO BE TALKING
ABOUT.
HE IS THE PERSON THAT IS THERE
COMFORTING AND REPRESENTING THE
NATION IN HIS EFFORT.
>> WELL SAID.
ON THAT POINT, I'M A LITTLE
UNCOMFORTABLE WITH THE IDEA OF
PRESIDENT BEING THE MORAL LEADER
OF OUR NATION.
I THINK FATHERS AND MOTHERS ARE
MORAL LEADERS OF THEIR HOMES.
SO LET'S NOT JUST OUTSOURCE ALL
OF OUR RESPONSIBILITY TO OUR
FAMILIES BY LOOKING TO THE
PRESIDENT TO SOLVE ALL OF OUR
PROBLEMS.
THIS IN PARTICULAR, LET'S TAKE
THIS UPON OURSELVES TO LEAD OUR
FAMILIES IN A BETTER PLACE.
>> Heather: THANK YOU ELLEN AND
MIKE.
>> Gregg: COMING UP, WE'LL HAVE
MORE ON THE PRESIDENT'S UP
COMING VISIT TO CONNECTICUT.
HE IS ALREADY THERE AS HE
PREPARES TO MEET THE VICTIMS'
FAMILIES BEFORE ATTENDING AN
INTERFAITH MEMORIAL SERVICE TO
REMEMBER THE LIVES YOUNG AND
OLDER, THOSE WHO WERE LOST IN
THE TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
:
EAT GOOD FATS.
AVOID BAD.
DON'T GO OVER 2000...
1200 CALORIES A DAY.
CARBS ARE BAD. CARBS ARE GOOD.
THE STORY KEEPS CHANGING.
SO I'M NOT LISTENING...
TO ANYONE BUT MYSELF.
I KNOW BETTER NUTRITION
WHEN I SEE IT:
GREAT GRAINS.
GREAT GRAINS CEREAL STARTS
WHOLE AND STAYS WHOLE.
SEE THE SEAM?
MORE PROCESSED FLAKES LOOK
NOTHING LIKE NATURALRAINS.
YOU CAN'T ARGUE WITH
NUTRITION YOU CAN SEE.
GREAT GRAINS.
SEARCH GREAT GRAINS
AND SEE FOR YOURSELF.
FOR MULTI GRAIN FLAKES TT ARE
ANXCELLENT SOURCE OF FIBER
TRY GREAT GRAINS
BANANA NUT CRUNCH
AND CRANBERRY ALMOND CRUNCH.
>> FOX COVERAGE OF THE TRAGEDY
IN NEWTOWN CONTINUES WITH JUST
TWO HOURS UNTIL THE COMMANDER IN
CHIEF ADDRESSES ONE OF THE MOST
HORRIFYING MASS SHOOTINGS IN
AMERICAN HISTORY AS WE LEARN
MORE OF THE INVESTIGATION INTO
THE LIVES LOST IN THIS
MINDBOGGLING ACT OF VIOLENCE.
>> WELCOME TO A BRAND NEW
AMERICAN'S NEWS HEADQUARTERS.
>>Gregg: THE PRESIDENT ON THE
GROUND, NOW, IN CONNECTICUT, AS
HE MEETS WITH FAMILIES OF THE
VICTIMS BEFORE ATTENDING AN
INTERFAITH MEMORIAL SERVICE AND
ADDRESSING A NATION IN MOURNING
AFTER THE LIVES THAT WERE LOST.
AND NOW, ED, TELL US WHAT THE
PRESIDENT WILL BE DOING THERE.
>>Reporter: WELL, IT IS A
COLD, DARK NIGHT HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
IT HAS BEEN ROUGH, OBVIOUSLY, ON
THE COMMUNITY FOR SEVERAL DAYS
BUT YOU CAN FEEL HOW RAW IT IS,
NOT JUST THE WEATHER BUT THE
EMOTIONS, PEOPLE GOING THROUGH A
TRAUMA.
ONE MAN KNEW TWO PEOPLE KILLED
AT THE SCHOOL, A TEACHER AND A
PRINCIPAL.
FOR THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES, NEW INFORMATION THIS
HOUR.
HE WROTE MOST OF THE SPEECH
HIMSELF MAKING IT CLEAR, AGAIN,
THIS IS DEEPLY PERSONAL FOR HIM
AS WE HEARD HIM TALK FRIDAY IN
THE WHITE HOUSE BRIEFING ROOM
WHEN HE CHOKED BACK TEARS.
HE HAD TO PAUSE DURING THE
REMARKS BECAUSE HE WAS THINKING
AS A PARENT, NOT JUST AS
PRESIDENT.
HE'LL MEET WITH THE FAMILIES
OF THE VICTIMS HERE NEAR THE
HIGH SCHOOL BEHIND ME WHERE THE
PRAYER VIGIL WILL BE.
SOME OF THE VICTIMS, SUCH YOUNG
CHILDREN, MAKES IT MORE
DIFFICULT FOR EVERYONE TO DEAL
WITH.
HE ALSO WILL MEET WITH FIRST
RESPONDERS THANK THEM.
THEY OBVIOUSLY HAD HEROIC
SACRIFICES NOT JUST RESPONDING
TO THE SCENE BUT IN TERMS OF
COUNSELING AND RESPONSE TO
PEOPLE IN THIS COMMUNITY SO THE
PRESIDENT WANTS TO THANK THEM.
HE WILL MAKE REMARKS.
IMPORTANT TO NOTE WHILE THE BIG
DEBATE HAS BEEN GOING ON ABOUT
GUN CONTROL, WE ARE NOT
ANTICIPATING THE PRESIDENT WILL
ADDRESS THAT.
>>Gregg: CERTAINLY WE HAVE
BEEN HEARING THE POLITICIANS
TALKING ABOUT THAT THROUGHOUT
THE DAY AND YESTERDAY, BUT THE
PRESIDENT DOESN'T FEEL THIS IS
THE APPROPRIATE VENUE, CORRECT?
>>Reporter: THAT IS THE SENSE.
FRIDAY, IN THE BRIEFING ROOM, HE
HINTED IN THE SECOND TERM IN
OFFICE AFTER BEING SWORN IN
JANUARY 20, HE WANTS TO SEE
DEMOCRATS AND REPUBLICANS AND
INDEPENDENCES COME TOGETHER ON
WHAT HE CALLED MEANINGFUL
ACTION.
WE HAVE HEARD CRITICS WHETHER IT
IS NEW YORK CITY MAYOR OR
DEMOCRATS IN THE PRESIDENT'S
PARTY, THEY HAVE HEARD THIS SO
MANY TIMES BEFORE, ONE TRAGEDY
AFTER ANOTHER BUT THERE HAS NOT
BEEN ACTION.
BUT IT HAS BEEN CLEAR IN TALKING
TO THE WHITE HOUSE OFFICIALS,
THE PRESIDENT DOESN'T BELIEVE
THIS IS THE TIME AND PLACE AS
THE FAMILIES ARE GRIEVING TO
TALK ABOUT SOMETHING THAT IS A
POLITICAL ISSUE.
WHAT HE HINTED ON FRIDAY
SUGGESTS IN THE DAYS AND WEEKS
AHEAD HE BELIEVES THIS SHOULD BE
A DEBATE IN THIS COUNTRY AND
LEGISLATIVE ACTION.
THE PRECISE SPECIFICS WILL BE
DEBATED.
>>Gregg: THANK YOU, ED HENRY,
IN NEW TOWN.
THANK YOU.
>>Heather: STARTING AT 6:00
P.M. EASTERN FOR COVERAGE OF THE
PRESIDENT'S VISIT TO NEWTOWN AND
THE INTERFAITH VIGIL HE WILL
ATTEND THE PROGRAM IS HOSTED BY
FOX NEWS CHANNEL BRET BAIER
HAPPENING LIVE RIGHT HERE ON
FOX.
>>Gregg: DISTURBING
DEVELOPMENTS IN THE CURT CUT --
CONNECTICUT SHOOTING, THE POLICE
SAY THE GUNMAN HAD A MASSIVE
ARSENAL OF FIREPOWER INCLUDING
HUNDREDS OF BULLETS.
MIKE?
>>Reporter: YES, HUNDREDS OF
ROUNDS WERE FIRED ACCORDING TO
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE.
MOST CAME FROM A PRIMARY WEAPON
USED IN THE ATTACK, THE ASSAULT
RIFLE COUPLED WITH HIGH
CAPACITY 30-ROUND CLIPS.
HE CARRIED TWO SIDE ARMS AND ONE
OF THE HANDGUNS WAS USED BY THE
GUNMAN TO KILL HIMSELF, ANOTHER
WEAPON WAS INVOLVED ACCORDING TO
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE, A
SHOTGUN LEFT OUT IN THE CAR IN
THE PARKING LOT.
BEYOND THAT, POLICE SAY THEY ARE
GATHERING INFORMATION AND
EVIDENCE RELATED TO THE ONE
QUESTION WE ALL WANT ANSWERED:
WHY DID THIS HAPPEN?
THEY NOT GOING TO OFFER UP
PARTIAL INFORMATION ON A MOTIVE.
>> THAT WILL COME AS WE FINISH
THE INVESTIGATION.
WE SIMPLY CANNOT PIECEMEAL IT.
WE DON'T HAVE A SPECIFIC REASON
TO STAND HERE AND SAY THIS
OCCURRED.
WE WILL AND WE ARE SEARCHING
DILIGENTLY AND NONSTOP TO ANSWER
THAT QUESTION.
>> WE LEARNED TODAY THAT
AUTOPSIES WERE COMPLETED ON THE
FINAL TWO BODIES TO BE REMOVED
FROM THE CRIME SCENES, THE
BODIES OF THE GUNMAN AND HIS
MOTHER.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER SAYS SHE
WAS KILLED BY MULTIPLE WOUNDS TO
THE HEAD.
THERE ARE MORE DETAILS FROM THE
ASSOCIATED PRESS SAYING SHE WAS
KILLED WHILE LAYING IN HER BED
AND STILL WEARING HER NIGHT
CLOTHES AND HE KILLED HIMSELF
WITH A SINGLE BULLET.
>> THANK YOU FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THANK YOU.
>>Heather: TEACHERS INSIDE THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
WHEN THE STUDENTS HEARD THE
SHOTS ARE SPEAKING OUT.
>> AS NEWS CREWS CROWDED THE
STREETS SUPPORT FOR THE VICTIMS
FILLED THE WINDOWS OF THE
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT CENTER.
ANGELS WERE PLACED ATOP TWO
TREES AND A MEMORIAL FOR
STUDENTS AND STAFF MEMBERS SHE
KNEW AND LOVED.
>> SHE WAS IN HER 2nd GRADE
CLASS THAT MORNING AND SHE HEARD
A NOISE.
>> I HEARD WHAT SOUNDED LIKE
GLASS BREAKING AND I WENT OUT TO
SEE WHAT IT WAS AND I REALIZED
IT WAS NOT GLASS BREAKING AND I
WENT INTO THE CLASSROOM, I
CALLED FOR MY TEACHER TO DO A
LOCKDOWN, I ESCORTED THE 16 KIDS
TO A SAFE CORNER, CALLED 9-1-1,
AND LISTENED TO THEIR
INSTRUCTIONS AND WAITED FOR
HELP.
>> WHEN THE SUSPECTED GUNMAN
WENT ON A SHOOTING RAMPAGE
THROUGH HER SCHOOL, SHE AND THE
CLASSROOM TEACHER KEPT THE 16
CHILDREN CALM.
>> KIDS ARE RESILIENT.
WE GAVE THEM BACKS, WE HELD
HANDS, WE TOLD THEM THEY WERE
OKAY.
>> SHE WAS INSIDE THE SCHOOL
WITH THE STUDENTS HER SON AND
DAUGHTER AND HUSBAND ALL FIRST
RESPONDERS FEARED FOR HER SAFETY
AS THEY WORKED TO KEEP OTHERS
SAFE.
>> IT WAS SCARY BUT SHE HAD HER
CELL ON ON SO WE HAD CONTACT.
OUR WORRY WAS MAKING SURE THAT
EVERYONE ELSE WAS SAFE.
>> WE WILL GET THROUGH THIS.
I HAVE LOST FRIENDS, STUDENTS.
>>Heather: THAT WAS WFXG FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>>Gregg: THE FIRST FUNERAL IS
SET FOR SIX-YEAR-OLD TOMORROW,
BURIED IN FAIRFIELD,
CONNECTICUT.
THE FAMILY REMEMBERS HIM AS
INTELLIGENT AND GENTLE BUT WITH
A RAMBUNCTIOUS STREAK.
HIS TWIN SISTER WAS ASSIGNED TO
A DIFFERENT CLASSROOM AND SHE
SURVIVED.
THE FAMILY SAYS NOAH CONSIDERED
HIS TWIN SISTER HIS VERY BEST
FRIEND.
THEY WERE INSEPARATABLE.
>>Heather: 20 CHILDREN WERE
KILLED AT THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
AND NOW SOME OF THE FAMILIES ARE
SPEAKING OUT ABOUT THEIR
PRECIOUS CHILDREN AND WE ARE
HEARING FROM THE FAMILIES WHOSE
CHILDREN SURVIVEED.
MOLLY LINE IS OUTSIDE THE HIGH
SCHOOL.
WE KNEW THIS WOULD BE THE NEXT
PHASE OF WHAT HAPPENED, MOLLY.
>>Reporter: WE ARE SEEING THE
FACES OF THE CHILDREN, AND
HEARING THE STORIES OF HOW THEY
SPENT THEIR TIME AND THE LOVED
ONES THAT WILL MISS HIM.
DANIEL, THE YOUNGEST OF THREE
YOUNG, A FIRST GRADER AND HE
LOVED TO PLAY SOCCER.
SIX WOMEN WERE MURDERED
INCLUDING THE PRINCIPAL OF SANDY
HOOK.
SHE WAS REMEMBERED AS A HERO WHO
TRIED TO STOP HIM THE SHE WAS A
PASSIONATE EDUCATOR.
AND A THIRD GRADER SAYS SHE
WOULD GET DOWN AND CONNECT WITH
THE KIDS ON THEIR LEVEL.
>> DAWN WAS PHENOMENAL.
I HAD SEEN HER ABOUT EVERY
MORNING AS PART OF THE BEFORE
AND AFTER SCHOOL PROGRAM AT THE
SCHOOL.
EACH DAY, SHE WAS SO CARE ASKING
GOT TO THE CHILDREN'S LEVEL AND
PARTICIPATED IN SO MANY
ACTIVISTS WITH THE CHILDREN AND
DRESSED UP WHEN SHE HAD A SOCK
HOCK AND DANCED WITH THE
CHILDREN.
THIS YEAR, THEY SOLD 3,000 BOOKS
AND SHE DRESSED UP AS A BOOK
FAIRY.
>>Heather: SHE IS REMEMBERED
AS ONE OF THE HEROES.
THERE WERE SIX WOMEN.
THERE ARE SO MANY STORIES OF
THEIR BRAVERY.
WE WILL HEAR MANY OF THEM IN THE
COMING DAYS.
>>Heather: DIFFICULT DAYS
AHEAD.
MOLLY, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>>Gregg: AN NFL PLAYER PAYING
A TRIBUTE, VICTOR CRUZ HONORING
THE MEMORY OF A SIX-YEAR OLD,
LIMIT JACK WAS A BIG FAN OF CRUZ
AND HE REMEMBERED HIM BY WRITING
"JACK PINTO MY HERO THIS ONE'S
FOR YOU ON HIS GLOVES.
ALL GIANTS PLAYERS WORK SHES ON
THEIR HELMETS TODAY FOR SANDY
SHOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>>Heather: WE HAVE OTHER
STORIES, THE TUG OF WAR IN
NEGOTIATIONS TO AVOID THE
LOOMING FISCAL CLIFF WITH THE
JANUARY 1 DEADLINE APPROACHING,
IS THERE ANY REAL PROGRESS BEING
MADE?
>>Gregg: THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL TRAGEDY LEADING MANY TO
WONDER WHAT WOULD CAUSE SOMEONE
TO DO SUCH A HORRIFIC ACT?
[ Male Announcer ]
RED LOBSTER'S
HITTING THE STREETS
TO TELL REAL PEOPLE ABOUT
OUR NEW 15 UNDER $15 MENU.
OH MY GOODNESS!
OH MY GOSH,
THIS LOOKS AMAZING!
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR NEW MAINE STAYS!
15ENTREES UNDER $15,
SEAFOOD, CHICKEN AND MORE!
OOTHE TILAPIAWITH ROASTEDEGETAB!
I'M ACTUALLY LOOKING AT
THE WO GRILLED CHICKEN
WITH PORTOBELLO WINE SAUCE.
AT PORK CHOP
WAS GREAT!
NO MORE
FAST FOOD FRIDAY'S!
WE'RE GOING TO GO
TO RED LOBSTER.
YEP.
[ Male Announcer ]
COME TRY OUR NEW MENU
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
SALAD, SANDWICHES, AND MORE.
I HAVE A COLD,
AND I TOOK NYQUIL,
BUT I'M STILL "STUBBED" UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT DOESN'T HAVE A DECONGESTANT.
NO WAY.
[ Male Announcer ] SORRY.
Alka-Seltzer Plus FIGHTS
YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A FAST ACTING
DECONGESTANT
TO RELIEVE YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
[ sighs ] THANKS!
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus.
♪ OH
WHAT A RELIEF IT IS! ♪
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
AND SAVE $1
VISIT Alka-Seltzer ON FACEBOOK.
GIVES YOU 1% CASH BACK
ON ALL PURCHASES,
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS.
AND EVERYONE LIKES 50% MORE...
[ Midwestern/Chicago accent ]
CHEDDAR! YEAH!
50 PERCENT MORE
[yodeling] YODEL-AY-EE-OO.
50% MORE FLASH.
[ Southern accent ]
50 PERCENT MORE TATERS.
THAT'S WHERE TOTS COME FROM.
[ Male Announcer ] THE
Capital One Cash Rewards Card
GIVES YOU
1% CASH BACK
ON EVERY
PURCHASE
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS
ON THE CASH YOU EARN.
IT'S THE CARD FOR PEOPLE
WHO LIKE MORE CASH.
50% MORE SPY STUFF.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
THIS CAR IS TOO SMALL.
>>Gregg: SECRETARY OF STATE,
HILLARY CLINTON RECOVERING AT
HOME, AFTER FAINTING AND
SUFFERING A CONCUSSION.
SHE WAS ADVISED TO REST AND
CANCEL ALL WORK EVENTS FOR A
WEEK.
>> GROWING MISERY IN THE
PHILIPPINES AFTER A TIE FOOTBALL
WITH A DEATH TOLL OVER 1,000.
MORE THAN 800 ARE MISSING.
>> IN SPAIN, MORE THAN 5,000
MEDICAL WORKERS TAKING TO THE
STREETS PROTESTING BUDGET CUTS
AND PLANS TO PARTLY PRIVATIZE
THE COUNTRY'S HEALTH CARE
SERVICE.
>>Heather: THE SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT IS ONE OF THE
DEADLIEST IN UNITED STATES
HISTORY AND BY TARGETING VERY
YOUNG PEOPLE ONE OF THE MOST
HORRIFIC.
MANY ARE ASKING WHAT COULD CAUSE
SOMEONE TO DO SUCH A HORRIBLE
THING.
MY NEXT GUEST HAS BEEN A FORMER
F.B.I. PROFILER AND AUTHOR OF
"DANGEROUS INSTINCTS."
BASED ON WHAT WE HAVE BEEN TOLD
SO FAR, BY WHAT WE KNOW, DO YOU
THINK THAT WE ARE IN I CLOSER TO
KNOWING WHY?
>>Guest: WELL, WE ARE GETTING
CLOSER TO KNOWING WHY.
I THINK THE LAW ENFORCEMENT
FOLKS THAT ARE CONDUCTING THE
INVESTIGATION ARE BEING
PARTICULARLY CAREFUL, TO BE
EXACT AND PRECISE ABOUT THE
INFORMATION THEY PROVIDE ONCE
THEY COMPLETE THE INVESTIGATION
BECAUSE THEY KNOW THAT PEOPLE
ARE EMOTIONAL AND ANGRY SO LAW
ENFORCEMENT WILL BE VERY CAREFUL
IT IS RIGHT ON THE MONEY AND
ACCURATE SO PEOPLE WILL HAVE THE
BACKGROUND AND THE UNDERSTANDING
OF WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
>>Heather: LET'S TALK ABOUT
THE LATEST INFORMATION THAT HAS
COME OUT TODAY.
MIKE REPORTED REGARDING THE
AMOUNT OF THE WEAPONS USED, AN
ASSAULT RIFLE, A SHOTGUN IN THE
CAR, TWO HANDGUNS, HUNDREDS OF
ROUNDS OF AMMUNITION, AND
MULTIPLE ROUNDS OF AMMUNITION,
DOES THAT TELL YOU ANYTHING?
>>Guest: IT SAYS, AGAIN, THE
GUNMAN CAME THERE WITH THE
INTENTION TO KILL AT MANY PEOPLE
AS HE COULD CULL AND HE WAS
EQUIPPED TO DO THAT AND HE
BROUGHT WEAPONS THAT WOULD
GUARANTEE THAT.
HE DID NOT BRING A BOW AND ARROW
OR A SLINGSHOT.
HE BROUGHT WEAPONS OF MASS
DESTRUCTION.
THAT IS WHAT HE INTENDED TO DO.
BY USING MULTIPLE WEAPONS RATHER
THAN A SINGLE WEAPON, YOU
GUARANTEE YOURSELF THAT YOU ARE
GOING TO ACCOMPLISH THAT GOAL.
>>Heather: AN ASSAULT RIFLE
AGAINST SIX AND SEVEN-YEAR-OLD
INNOCENT CHILDREN.
WHAT ABOUT THE VICTIMS HE
PICKED.
DO YOU HAVE ANY ANSWERS?
>>Guest: THE CHOICE OF THE
VICTIMS IS VERY IMPORTANT.
THOSE VICTIMS ARE VERY
VULNERABLE.
THEY ARE HELPLESS INDIVIDUALS.
THEY SMALL CHILDREN.
THEY DON'T KNOW HOW TO RESPOND
TO A SITUATION LIKE THAT.
IN MY OPINION, WHEN YOU CHOOSE
VICTIMS WHO ARE LIKE THAT, YOU
VERY MUCH GUARANTEE YOU ARE
GOING TO GET NOTORIETY AND YOU
WILL STOP THE WORLD FOR A PERIOD
OF TIME.
IF THAT WAS HIS INTENTION HE DID
THAT BUT TO BE ABLE TO CARRY
THAT OUT YOU HAVE TO BE ABLE TO
DEHUMANIZE PEOPLE OR TO TURN
THEM INTO OBJECTS.
>>Heather: WE DISCOVERED ALSO
HE SHOT HIS MOTHER FIRST.
SHE WAS STILL IN HER PAJAMAS, IN
BED, SHOT HER REPEATEDLY
MULTIPLE TIME IN THE HEAD AND
GOT IN HER CAR AND DROVE TO THE
SCHOOL.
DO YOU BELIEVE, ALTHOUGH
INITIALLY IT WAS REPORTED SHE
WAS AT SCHOOL, THAT IS THOUGHT
TRUE, SHE WAS NOT A TEACHER, IS
THERE A CONNECTION BETWEEN THE
TWO?
>>Guest: THAT WOULD MAKE THE
MOST SENSE TO ME THIS IS A
CONNECTION BETWEEN THE TWO.
BUT SAY THERE ISN'T A CONNECTION
BETWEEN THE TWO.
JUST THE CHOICE OF SELECTING
SMALL CHILDREN BECOMES REALLY
IMPORTANT TO WHAT HE WANTED TO
ACCOMPLISH WHICH DID REQUIRE
INCREDIBLE ANGER AND INCREDIBLE
SENSE OF REVENGE AND A NEED TO
RETALIATE.
THAT INFORMATION WILL COME OUT
AS THE INVESTIGATION UNFOLDS.
TO TARGET THAT KIND OF A VICTIM
REQUIRES INTENSE ANGER TOWARD
PEOPLE THAT DON'T HAVE THE
CAPABILITY OF HAVING HURT YOU AT
ANY POINT IN THE PAST.
>>Heather: SOMETHING ELSE
INTERESTING ABOUT THE KILLER, HE
WAS 20 YEARS OLD AND IN THIS DAY
AND AGE 20-YEAR-OLDS USUALLY
HAVE AN EXTENSIVE DIGITAL
FOOTPRINT BUT HE DID NOT HAVE
FACEBOOK PAGE.
WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF THAT?
>>Guest: WELL, IN THE LAST
COUPLE OF CASES THAT WAS, IN
FACT, TRUE.
HIS INTERESTS MAY HAVE BEEN
FOCUSED ON SOMETHING ELSE.
WE HAVE PRECONCEIVED IDEAS THIS
IS WHAT IS TYPICAL IF A
20-YEAR-OLD AND WE MAY BE RIGHT
BUT WE CANNOT BE SURPRISED WHEN
WE SEE ATYPICAL BEHAVIOR BECAUSE
THE SHOOTERS DO NOT COME FROM
THE SAME PATTERN, AND ARE AN
ANOMALY.
WE DO HAVE TO ACCEPT THE FACT WE
ARE GOING TO SEE DISTINCT
DIFFERENCES AND DISTINCT
PATTERNS.
>>Heather: IS THERE ANYTHING
THAT COULD HAVE BEEN DONE TO
PREVENT THIS?
>>Guest: WELL, I HAVE BEEN
TALKING ABOUT THERE AND I HAVE
HEARD OTHER FOLKS TALK ABOUT IT.
THIS IS NOT SNAP BEHAVIOR, IT
WAS NOT AN IMPULSIVE ACT.
IT TOOK TIME TO GET THE GUNS.
IT TOOK TIME TO GET THE
AMMUNITION.
DURING THAT TIME, THE SHOOTER'S
BEHAVIOR WOULD HAVE BECOME EVEN
MORE DANGEROUS AND MORE ERRATIC
AND HIS CIRCLE WAS SMALL AND
THOSE CLOSE TO HIM WOULD HAVE
NOTICEED SOMETHING AS HE BEGAN
TO GET WORSE AND WORSE.
>>Heather: THANK YOU VERY MUCH
FOR THIS VERY GOOD INSIGHT.
>>Gregg: PRESIDENT OBAMA IS IN
CONNECTICUT AT THIS HOUR
ATTENDING AN INTERFAITH PRAYER
VIGIL THIS EVENING FOR VICTIMS
OF THE SANDY HOOK SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
WE ARE AWAITING THE REMARKS.
HE IS MEETING FIRST WITH THE
FAMILY MEMBERS OF THE CHILDREN.
>> THIS IS THE DARK OF THE THING
I HAVE EVER EXPERIENCED IN MY
LIFE AND VERY DRAMATIC AND JUST
HORRIFIC.
MY DOCTOR TOLD ME CALCIUM
IS EFFICIENTLY ABSORBED IN SMALL
CONTINUOUS AMOUNTS.
Citracal Slow Release
CONTINUOUSLY RELEASES CALCIUM
PLUS D
WITH EFFICIENT ABSORPTION
IN ONE DAILY DOSE.
Citracal Slow Release.
>>Heather: AT THE
TOP OF THE HOUR FOX NEWS WILL
BRING YOU FULL COVERAGE OF THE
PRESIDENT'S VISIT TO NEWTOWN AND
THE VIGIL HE WILL ATTEND.
THE PROGRAM IS ANCHORED BY BRET
BAIER WHO JOINS US LIVE FROM
WASHINGTON, DC WITH A PREVIEW.
>>Bret: PEOPLE ARE JUST
STARTING TO FILE IN TO THE
AUDITORIUM AT NEWTOWN HIGH
SCHOOL.
THIS IS WHERE THE VIGIL WILL
TAKE PLACE.
OBVIOUSLY, IT IS AN EMOTIONAL
NIGHT.
A SOMBER SET AND IT HAS BEEN
RAINING ALL DAY SETTING THE MOOD
FOR THE EMOTION THIS.
YOU CAN SEE A LIVE LOOK IN THE
AUDITORIUM RIGHT NOW.
THERE IS A SCHEDULE WITH MANY
DIFFERENT READINGS AND DIFFERENT
RELIGIOUS FIGURES FROM VARIOUS
CHURCHES AND SYNAGOGUES AND
PLACES OF WORSHIP AROUND THE
REGION THAT WILL SPEAK AT VIGIL.
PRAYERS FOR THE CHILDREN,
PRAYERS FOR THE VICTIMS, PRAYERS
FOR THE FAMILIES OF THE TRAGEDY.
WE WILL ALSO HEAR FROM A LOCAL
POLITICIAN, RATHER, LOCAL
POLITICIANS THROUGH THE CEREMONY
, WITH THE GOVERNOR
INTRODUCING PRESIDENT OBAMA.
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS ON THE GROUND
NOW.
HE WILL MEET WITH VICTIMS'
FAMILY MEMBERS AND FIRST
RESPONDERS.
HE WILL SPEAK.
HE HAS BEEN WORKING WITH A
SPEECHWRITER WE ARE TOLD BY THE
WHITE HOUSE POOL BUT THEY ARE
SAYING HE IS WORKING ON THE
REMARKS PERSONALLY.
IT IS A "CONSOLER IN CHIEF"
MOMENT, THAT NOT ONLY FOR
NEWTOWN, BUT, REALLY, FOR THE
NATION AS MANY AROUND THE WORLD,
AS WELL, AND THE COUNTRY ARE
DEALING WITH THIS TRAGEDY TODAY.
>>Heather: BRET, THIS IS THE
FOUR THE SUCH TRIP HE HAS TAKEN
DURING THE PRESIDENCY AND I KNOW
YOU HAVE LISTENED TO HIM EACH
TIME HE GOES TO THE COMMUNITIES
TO SPEAK FOLLOWING A MASS
SHOOTING.
AURORA WOULD, COLORADO, TUCSON,
FT. HOOD, AND HE ACTUALLY SHED A
TEAR ON FRIDAY WHEN HE FIRST
SPOKE ABOUT WHAT TRANSPIRED.
DO YOU EXPECT TO SEE THE SAME
EMOTION TONIGHT?
>>Bret: IT IS POSSIBLE.
YOU LOOK AT THE VIDEO ON FRIDAY,
THIS IS A FATHER OF TWO YOUNG
DAUGHTERS.
AS THE TRAGEDY HAS AFFECTED A
LOT OF PEOPLE, YOU JUST TALK TO
THEM AND IT AFFECTS PEOPLE.
IT AFFECTS THE PRESIDENT THE
SAME WAY TALKING TO PEOPLE
AROUND HIM.
HE WAS AFFECTED THIS WAY ON
FRIDAY.
ED HENRY HAS DONE SOME GREAT
REPORTING AROUND WHAT THIS
PRESIDENT HAS BEEN DEALING WITH
PUTTING THIS SPEECH TOGETHER.
HE IS GOING TO SPEAK FROM THE
HEART.
HE WILL NOT DEAL WITH ANYTHING
POLICY-WISE TONIGHT.
IT IS A BIG MOMENT FOR THIS
COMMUNITY FOR HEALING.
IT WILL TAKE A LONG-TERM AFTER
SOMETHING LIKE THIS FOR THAT
PLACE TO GET BEYOND ANYTHING.
>>Heather: I KNOW AS A DAD YOU
WILL LISTEN IN THAT RESPECT, AS
WELL.
>> THAT IS TONIGHT STARTING AT
6:00 P.M. EASTERN AND BRET WILL
HAVE FULL COVERAGE OF THE
INTERFAITH VIGIL.
>> AND THE UNITED NATIONS
AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE ASKED
PRESIDENT OBAMA TO HER
NAME FROM CONSIDERATION TO
BECOME THE NEXT SECRETARY OF
STATE.
THE AN RICE WAS CRITICIZED FOR
HER PUBLIC EXPLANATION OF THE
DEADLY BENGHAZI TERRORIST ACT
WHICH, OF COURSE, TURNED OUT TO
BE FALSE.
AND NOW OUR POLITICAL INSIDERS,
JOHN LEBOUTILLIER, AND PAT
CADDELL, AND DOUG SCHOEN, A FOX
NEWS CONTRIBUTOR AND FORMER
POLLSTER FOR BILL CLINTON.
DOUG, THE OP-ED OF THE MAT NOT,
IS A FULL CHEERLEADER FOR
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND I FELL OUT
OF THE CHAIR AND BROKE MY ELBOW
WHEN I READ THIS OP-ED THAT RIPS
INTO SUSAN RICE FOR BEING BEST
FRIENDS WITH BRUTAL AFRICAN
DICTATORS.
DOW JONES INDUSTRIAL>>Doug: A NE
SAME POINT AND OUR COLLEAGUES'
SENSE, THAT WAS THE END.
THE PRESIDENT UNDERSTOOD HE
COULD NOT GO FORWARD WITH HER
AFTER THAT.
IT WAS ONLY A MATTER OF TIME.
>> THIS WAS A PIECE IN THE "WALL
STREET JOURNAL" AND THAT
DEVASTATED HER, AND TODAY IN THE
"NEW YORK TIMES", THE STORY IN
THE REVIEW SECTION "WORST WAR IN
THE WORLD IS IN CONGO" SHE HAS
BEEN SUPPORTING THE PRESIDENT
WHO IS IS A FORMER CLIENT OF HE.
SHE SHOULD HAVE BEEN OUT OF
OFFICE AND SHOULD NOT BE AT THE
U.N., PUTTING HER FORMER
BUSINESS INTERESTS WITH PEOPLE
DYING BY THE HUNDREDS OF
THOUSANDS AND WHEN THE NOT MAT
DID THAT -- WHEN THE NOT -- "NEW
YORK TIMES" DID THAT AND THE
OP-ED, SHE WAS GONE.
>> WE ARE NOW GOING TO HAVE
HEARINGS THIS WEEK ON BENGHAZI
CHAIRED BY JOHN KERRY.
AND THE MAIN WITNESS WAS GOING
TO BE HILLARY CLINTON.
SINCE THIS WAS ANNOUNCED WE KNOW
THAT JOHN KERRY IS GOING TO BE
THE NEXT SECRETARY OF STATE.
>>Gregg: THE GUY WHO CALLED
ASSAD A REFORMER.
>> AND NOW MRS. CLINTON HAS A
STOMACH BUG AND SHE CANNOT
TESTIFY, SHE HAD A CONCUSSION.
>>Gregg: SO WE WILL NEVER
HEAR?
HE WILL BE CONFIRMED EASILY?
>> HE MADE THE RIGHT CALL FOR
JOHN McCAIN IN 2004 ASKING HIM
TO BE THE RUNNING MATE AND CHUCK
HAGEL SECRETARY OF DEFENSE WHO
OPPOSED SANCTIONS ON IRAN, HE
OBJECTED AND HE IS CONSIDERED,
AS YOU KNOW, IN ISRAEL, TO BE
VERY ANTIISRAEL AND HE IS
AGAINST ALL INTERVENTIONS.
WE WILL HAVE A POLITICAL
SECRETARY WHO WILL GET COVER AS
HE CONTINUES A FOREIGN POLICY
THAT MANY AMERICANS OBJECT TO.
>> HE WANTED A REPUBLICAN TO
LEAD THAT CHARGE.
>> YOU NEED A CHAIN SAW.
>> THE FISCAL CLIFF, WE WILL
TALK ABOUT THAT.
ON FRIDAY, WE DON'T KNOW WHAT
HAPPENED YESTERDAY BUT SPEAKER
PER IS OFFERING TO RAISE TAX
RATES ON INCOME ABOVE $1 MILLION
AND OBAMA IS HOLDING FIRM AT
$250,000.
>> THIS IS WHAT WE HAVE BEEN
TALKING ABOUT, THE BEGINNING OF
THE REPUBLICAN CAVE.
WHETHER THEY WILL CAVE ENOUGH TO
GET A DEAL BEFORE DECEMBER 31,
WE DON'T KNOW.
THIS IS UNILATERAL SURRENDER.
>> OBAMA WANTS MORE TAX
INCREASES THAN CUTS BUT MEMBERS
ARE THE OPPOSITE.
THIS IS THE FOX NEWS POLL, WHICH
IS THE BEST WAY TO DEAL WITH THE
COUNTRY'S BUDGET PROBLEM, AND 57
PERCENT SAY CUT THE BUDGET FOR
GOODNESS SAKE, CUT YOUR
SPENDING.
20 PERCENT SAY TAX INCREASES.
>> IT WILL NEVER HAPPEN.
IF ALL WE GET ARE HUGE TAX
INCREASES AND MINIMAL SPENDING
CUTS .
>> BECAUSE THE REPUBLICAN PARTY
AND SPEAKER BOEHNER IS A PERFECT
EXAMPLE, HE IS NEGOTIATING AND
CHUCK SCHUMER SAID $1 MILLION,
DEMAND THE PRESIDENT LAY OUT
CUTS AND FIGHT OVER THE DEBT
LIMIT BUT INSTEAD THEY ARE DOING
THIS IN PRIVATE AND IT WILL BE A
SERIES OF RETREATS.
>> THE MESSAGE IS, THEY IS NO
MESSAGE, NO ARGUMENT, NOTHING TO
SAY.
>> YOU REMEMBER THE DEBATES THEY
HAD TALKED ABOUT RAISING A
DOLLAR OF TAX FOR TEN DOLLARS OF
SPENDING CUTS.
NONE OF THEM RAISED THEIR HAND.
NOW, WE HAVE SPEAKER BOEHNER
RAISING HIS HAND TO RAISE TAXES
WITHOUT GETTING ANY SPENDING
CUTS.
>>Gregg: THE PRESIDENT IS
ARGUING 2-1 TAX INCREASES AND
HIS DOUBT COMMISSION SAID, NO,
NO, JUST THE OPPOSITE.
HE HAS A REPUBLICAN PARTY THAT
IS IN THE PROCESS OF DIVIDING
HOPELESSLY, SURRENDERING, AND,
JOHN, DO YOU THINK SPEAKER
BOEHNER CAN GET A DEAL LIKE THIS
THROUGH THE CAUCUS?
YOU HAVE BEEN THERE.
>> NO, THEY WILL NOT GET THAT.
THAT IS THE FEAR AND HE IS AWARE
OF IT AND HE HAS BEEN AWARE OF
IT SINCE AUGUST OF 2011.
THE FACT THAT HE OFFERED THIS
TAX INCREASE, HE HAS SUPPORT FOR
THAT.
>>Gregg: YOU THINK REPUBLICANS
WILL GET, BASED ON OUR LAST
CONVERSATION, YOU THINK
REPUBLICANS WILL GET THE BLAME
IF WE GO OVER THE FISCAL CLIFF.
THE "WALL STREET JOURNAL" WHO IS
TO BLAME IF NO COMPROMISE IS
REACHED?
AND 56 PERCENT AND SLIGHTLY
MORE, 24-19, REPUBLICANS OVER
DEMOCRATS.
>> BUT IF YOU ASK DEMOCRATS
VERSUS REPUBLICANS IT IS 2-1.
THE PROBLEM IS MOST PEOPLE DON'T
SEE THIS AS EVERYONE'S FAULT BUT
IF THEY HAVE TO CHOOSE, IT IS
THE REPUBLICANS' BLAME.
>> BUT, REMEMBER, PRESIDENT
OBAMA REACHED THE NADER
POLITICALLY ON THE BREAKDOWN OF
THE SPENDING.
BUT BACK TO A POINT YOU MADE ON
THIS, THE PRESIDENT IS NOT
INTERESTED IN CUTTING, HE IS
INTERESTED IN SPENDING.
HE WANTS MORE SPENDING AND MORE
TAX INCREASES BUT THE REPUBLICAN
FAILURE TO BE ABLE TO HAVE AN
ALTERNATIVE NARRATIVE WHICH THEY
NEVER HAD AND THEY NEVER --.
>>Gregg: HOLD THAT THOUGHT, WE
WILL TALK ABOUT THAT IN THE NEXT
SEGMENT.
BRAND NEW POLLS REVIEWING THE
POSSIBLE PROBLEMS FOR THE
REPUBLICAN PARTY.
OUR PANEL DEBATES PROBLEMS AND
POSSIBLE SOLUTIONS.
THAT IS NEXT.
AS PARENTS STRUGGLE TO EXPLAIN
THE IMAGES TO KIDS OF ALL AGES
WE WILL LOOK AT THE BEST WAYS TO
TALK ABOUT ALL OF THIS.
♪
[ engine revs ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THE MERCEDES-BENZ WINTER EVENT
IS BACK,
WITH THE PERFECT VEHICLE
THAT'S JUST RIGHT FOR YOU,
NO MATTER WHICH LIST YOU'RE ON.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
C250 FOR $349 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a
Droid Incredible 4G LTE
by HTC for $49.99.
>>Heather: WE ARE GETTING NEW
DAYLIGHTS IN THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL TRAGEDY SUSPECTING THE
GUNMAN MAY HAVE HAD A MORE
GRUESOME PLAN IN MIND.
HERE IS WHAT WE KNOW.
ADAM LANZA SHOT HIS MOTHER IN
THE HEAD FOUR TIMES BEFORE
RETURNING TO SANDY HOOK SCHOOL
CARRYING HUNDREDS OF BULLETS.
HE KILLED HIMSELF.
ALL EVIDENCE ACCORDING TO SOME
EXPERTS THAT THE GUNMAN WAS
INTENT ON DOING WERE MORE DAMAGE
INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
>>Gregg: AND WE HAVE JOHN
LEBOUTILLIER AND PAT CADDELL,
AND DOUG SCHOEN.
THE POPULARITY CONTEST, IF YOU
WILL, POSITIVES AND NEGATIVES
AND AT THE BOTTOM HERE ON THE
CHART, WITH THE WORST RATINGS,
THE REPUBLICAN PARTY, THE BRAND
HAS BEEN HURT DURING THE
ELECTION AND IT HAS BEEN HURT
BADLY.
THE REASON FOR THAT IS THERE IS
NOT A POSITIVE MESSAGE THAT
PEOPLE ASSOCIATE WITH THE
REPUBLICANS, NOT JOBS, OR
ECONOMIC GROWTH OR CUTTING
SPENDING, AND NOT REFORMING
ENTITLEMENTS, NOTHING.
BOTTOM LINE, UNLESS THE
REPUBLICANS FIX THIS THEY WILL
BE IN DEEP, DEEP TROUBLE GOING
FORWARD.
>> WE HAVE ANOTHER NUMBER HERE
WE WILL GO TO SHOWING THE SECOND
WEEK IN A ROW ON THE GENERIC
BALLOT.
>>Gregg: TEN POINTS FOR THE
SECOND WEEK IN A ROW, THIS IS
THE WORST RESULT SINCE 2009, THE
BRAND DAMAGE, NOT ONLY DO THEY
NOT HAVE A POSITIVE MESSAGE THEY
DO NOT HAVE A CONTRAST CHALLENGE
TO THE PRESIDENT.
THEY ARE STILL IN THE PROCESS OF
SWOPPING UNDER THE RUG THE RNC
ANNOUNCING THE APPOINTMENT OF
BARBOUR WHO WAS AT CROSSROADS OF
THE FORMER CHAIRMAN, AND HE WILL
HEAD UP TO WHITEWASH THE RNC AND
CROSSROADS OVER WHAT HAPPENS IN
THE ELECTION AND THE FAILURE AND
WHAT IT MEANS.
>> I WROTE TO A BUNGLER AND HE
TOLD ME TODAY HE IS DONE.
FINISHED.
IN MORE MONEY.
HE SAID I --.
>> THAT IS WHY THE CONFERENCE
WAS CANCELED IN JANUARY, THE
MEETING.
>> THERE ARE TWO THINGS.
THE BIG PICTURE IS, DOUG SAID
THE REPUBLICANS ARE IN TROUBLE.
IT IS NOT JUST NOW.
THE FRIENDS ARE BAD AND NOTHING
IS DONE TO REVERSE IT.
NOT JUST ROMNEY BUT A SERIES OF
EVENTS.
THE IMAGE OF THE REPUBLICAN
PARTY IS NASTY, NEGATIVE, MEAN.
NOT LIKE IT WAS UNDER REAGAN
WHERE IT WAS NICE.
YES, IT WAS STRONG.
>> WHO BEARS THE RESPONSIBILITY?
>> A LOT OF PEOPLE.
>> ALL THE CONSULTANTS GETTING
ALL THIS MONEY, AND THE ANSWER
IS THE REPUBLICAN ESTABLISHMENT
HAS NO VISION.
WE HAVE NUMBERS, IF YOU ASK
PEOPLE ARE THEY FOR SMALLER OR
BIGGER GOVERNMENT, THEY ARE FOR
SMALLER.
>> THERE IS SUPPORT AT GRASS
ROOTS BUT THEY WILL CANNOT
TRANSLATE IT.
>> YOU HAVE TO LOOK TO
LEADERSHIP IN THE HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES AND THE SENATE.
>> AND THOSE TWO DO NOT TALK TO
EACH OTHER.
>> THEY DO NOT HAVE THE SAME
GAME PLAN NEGOTIATING WITH THE
PRESIDENT.
YOU WOULD THINK THE PARTY WOULD
BE UNIFIED.
>>Gregg: AND ANOTHER POLL, FOX
NEWS, 65 PERCENT SAY GOVERNMENT
IS DOWN RIGHT BROKEN AND 26
PERCENT SAY JUST OKAY.
>> EVERYONE WANTS CHANGE,
FUNDAMENTAL CHANGE, AND THE
REPUBLICANS ARE NOT DOING GREAT,
WHAT THEY ARE NOT DOING IS
GIVING A PLAN THAT IS FISCALLY
PRUDENT OFFERING A WAY OUT.
>> YOU DO NOT NEED TWO PARTIES
DEFENDING THE BROKEN WASHINGTON,
DC.
YOU NEED A PARTY THAT IS THE
ANTIPARTY OF THAT AND THE
REPUBLICANS SHOULD DO THAT BUT
THEY ARE NOT BECAUSE THE
REPUBLICAN ESTABLISHMENT IS AN
ESTABLISHMENT WASHINGTON PARTY
AND I MUST SAY, IT IS --.
>> ARE WE IN THE 1850'S WITH THE
BIRTH ULTIMATELY OF THE NEW
PARTY.
>> THERE IS A SUPERMAJORITY THAT
IS A MODERATE CENTER RIGHT
PARTY.
IF THE REPUBLICANS CHOOSE NOT TO
SPEAK TO THAT, THEY COULD BE
GONE.
>> THE CLIFF CLIFF IS THE TOPIC
OF THE DAY AND IT WILL BE UNTIL
JANUARY 1 UNLESS SOMETHING IS
DONE.
>> OR LONGER.
60 PERCENT OF REPUBLICANS WANT
TO COMPROMISE AND 61 PERCENT SAY
WE DO WANT YOU TO RAISE TAXES IF
YOU MUST ON THE WEALTHY.
NOW, IF SPEAKER BOEHNER DOES
THAT, AND HE IS OFFERING THAT,
WHAT, THEN?
>> IF HE GETS SIGNIFICANT
SPENDING CUTS AS PART OF THE
DEAL, HE WILL SURVIVE AS
SPEAKER, THE REPUBLICANS WILL
SURVIVE AND THEY WILL HAVE
SOMETHING TO CAMPAIGN ON.
THAT IS THE TRADE.
>> THEY HAVE NOT ARTICULATED THE
NEED TO CUT SPENDING AS PART OF
A PRO GROWTH STRATEGY IN A WAY
THEY NEED TO DO.
>> THEY ARE BEING KILLED ON
MESSAGE.
>>Gregg: IT IS A SHAME WE ARE
OUT OF TIME.
I WANT TO ASK YOU ABOUT 44
PERCENT THE DEMOCRATS ARE SANTA
CLAUS, SANTA IS A DEMOCRAT.
THEY THINK SANTA IS NICE.
SANTA REDISTRIBUTES WEALTH AND
THE REPUBLICANS ARE SCROOGE.
>>Gregg: GENTLEMAN, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
MORE FROM OUR POLITICAL INSIDERS
EACH MONDAY AT 10:30 A.M., AND
WILL BE BACK HERE ON SUNDAY, OF
COURSE.
>>Heather: AS WE CONTINUE OUR
COVERAGE OF THE TRAGIC SHOOTING
IN CONNECTICUT LAST WEEK THERE
IS A GROWING FOCUS ON HOW TO
DISCUSS THE TRAGEDY WITH
CHILDREN WITHOUT ADDING TO THE
FEAR AND TRAUMA MANY MAY ALREADY
FEEL.
WE WILL DISCUSS THAT WITH OUR
PEDIATRIC EXPERTS UP NEXT.
ULENT,
LIKE OURENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
PREGO?!
BUT I'VE BOUGHT RAGU FOR YEARS.
[ Thinking ] WONDER WHAT OTHER
QUESTIONABLE CHOICES I'VE MADE?
I CHOOSE DATE NUMBER 2!
WHOOO!
[ sigh of relief ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHOOSE TASTE. CHOOSE PREGO.
YOU'VE REACHED THE AGE
WHERE YOU DON'T BACK DOWN
FROM A CHALLENGE.
THIS IS THE AGE OF KNOWING
HOW TO MAKE THINGS HAPPEN.
SOWHY LET
ERECTILE DYSFUNCTION
GET IN YOUR WAY?
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT VIAGRA.
20 MILLION MEN ALREADY HAVE.
ASK YOUR DOCTOR IF YOUR HEART
IS HEALTHY ENOUGH FOR SEX.
DO NOT TAKE VIAGRA IF YOU TAKE
NITRATES FOR CHEST PAIN;
IT MAY CAUSE AN UNSAFE DROP
IN BLOOD PRESSURE.
SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE
HEADACHE, FLUSHING,
UPSET STOMACH,
AND ABNORMAL VISION.
TO AVOID LONG-TERM INJURY,
SEEK IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
FOR AN ERECTION
LASTING MORE THAN FOUR HOURS.
STOP TAKING VIAGRA
AND CALL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU EXPERIENCE
A SUDDEN DECREASE OR LOSS
IN VISION OR HEARING.
THIS IS THE AGE
OF TAKING ACTION.
VIAGRA.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR.
But when I was in an accident...
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
So I never missed a beat.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.
>>Heather: MANY PARENTS ARE
TRYING TO SHIELD THEIR CHILDREN
FROM IMAGES FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>>Gregg: THAT CAN BE TOUGH IN
THIS MEDIA AGE.
WHAT CAN PARENTS DO TO MAKE SURE
IT DOES NOT TAKE AN EMOTIONAL
TOLL ON OUR CHILDREN?
WE HAVE A SPOKESPERSON FOR THE
AMERICAN ACADEMY OF PEDIATRICS.
THANKS FOR BEING WITH US,
DOCTOR.
I HAVE TEENAGED KIDS SO THIS IS
NOT PRACTICAL, BUT FOR YOUNGER
CHILDREN, TURN OFF THE TV?
>>Guest: MY CHILDREN ARE EIGHT
AND TEN, OUR TELEVISION IS NOT
ON AT ALL.
I DON'T WANT THEM TO SEE THE
IMAGES.
I TALKED TO THEM.
I THINK IT IS IMPORTANT IF YOU
HAVE CHILDREN THAT ARE GOING TO
BE EXPOSED, CHILDREN THAT WILL
GO TO SCHOOL AND HEAR CHILDREN
TALKING ABOUT, IT IS IMPORTANT
THEY HEAR IT FROM YOU FIRST SO
THEY GET THE FACTS AND DETAILS
AND THE EXPERT THEY NEED.
>>Heather: YOU HAVE TEENS SO
IT IS DIFFICULT TO SHIELD THEM.
>>Heather: THEY ARE RETURNING
TO SCHOOL.
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THOSE
CHILDREN?
>>Guest: YOU WANT TO BE VERY
CAREFUL IN THE WAY YOU TELL THE
STORY.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO GIVE THEM ALL
THE SMALL DETAILS.
YOU GIVE THEM CONCRETE FACTS.
A EXTERNAL THING HAPPENED.
THERE WAS A BIG SHOOTING.
A LOT PEOPLE WERE INJURED.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO TELL THEM THE
AGE OF THE PEOPLE.
IF THEY ASK QUESTIONS, YOU NEED
TO ANSWER THE QUESTIONS.
WHEN YOU GIVE YOUR SHORT STORY,
YOU ASK THEM, DO YOU HAVE ANY
QUESTIONS, HOW DO YOU FEEL IN
YOU WANT TO ON THE DOOR FOR WHAT
THEIR RESPONDS ARE.
SOME KIDS AT THE AGE OF EIGHT OR
TEN DON'T HAVE THE DEVELOPMENTAL
MATURITY TO UNDERSTAND THAT IS
GOING ONS THEY HEAR IT AND MOVE
ON AND OTHER CHILDREN WILL BE
AFRAID IT WILL HAPPEN TO THEM.
>>Gregg: WHAT I TRY TO STRESS
IS THERE ARE LITERALLY MANY
SCHOOLS OPERATING EACH DAY AND
IT DOES NOT HAPPEN IN THE OTHER
SCHOOLS BUT THIS IS AN
ABERRATION.
SHOULD YOU CONVEY THAT?
>>Guest: YOU WANT KIDS TO FEET
-- FEEL SAFE.
YOU WANT DID SHOW THEM THIS IS
THE EXCEPTION AND NOT THE RULE.
YOU TALK ABOUT ALL THE PEOPLE
THAT ARE THERE TO PROTECT THEM,
HOW AS A PARENT I WILL ALWAYS DO
EVERYTHING I CAN TO PROTECT YOU
TO KEEP YOU SAFE.
TEACHERS WILL DO THE SAME THING
AND POLICE OFFICERS AND
FIREFIGHTERS, AND A VILLAGE OF
PEOPLE AROUND YOU THAT WILL DO
EVERYTHING YOU CAN TO PROTECT
YOU.
>>Heather: ENCOURAGE THEM WHEN
THEY COME HOME FROM SCHOOL ON
MONDAY TO SHARE WITH YOU WHAT
THEY HEARD FROM OTHER STUDENTS.
>>Guest: ABSOLUTELY.
MONDAY NIGHT DINNER IS
INCREDIBLY IMPORTANT TIME FOR
REFLECTION WITH FAMILY AND A
TIME TO CELEBRATE YOUR OWN
FAMILY AND BE THANKFUL FOR WHAT
YOU HAVE AS YOU COME TOGETHER.
MONDAY NIGHT IS GOING TO A VERY
IMPORTANT NIGHT FOR FAMILIES.
>>Gregg: PARENTS NEED TO BE
VIGILANT.
>>Guest: YOU WANT TO WATCH OUT
FOR ANY DIFFERENT BEHAVIOR, IF
THEY ACT OUT OR HAVE DIFFICULTY
EATING OR COMPLAINING OF
HEADACHES AND ABDOMINAL PAIN,
TAKE IT SERIOUSLY AT A TIME LIKE
THIS, PARTICULARLY, ASKING MORE
AND MORE QUESTIONS OF HOW THEY
FEEL.
>>Heather: THERE IS AN
ASSOCIATION WITH THE KILLER IN
THIS INSTANCE, ADAM, THAT HE WAS
POSSIBLY DIAGNOSED WITH SOME
SORT OF MENTAL DISABILITY, A
DISORDER, AND THEY TALKED ABOUT
ASPERGERS AS A POSSIBLE BUT IT
IS NOT CONFIRMED.
>>Guest: ASPERGER IS NOT
HOMICIDAL BEHAVIOR, AND THIS IS
MORE A DISORDER OF
COMMUNICATION.
CHILDREN AND ADULTS OF ASPERGERS
HAVE A HARD TIME MAKING
CONTACTING AND PICKING UP SOCIAL
CUES LIKE A SENSE OF HUMOR OR
FIGURES OF SPEECH AND
INVESTIGATION.
SO, WE ARE REALLY TALKING ABOUT
AN ENTIRELY DIFFERENT SITUATION
THAN SOMEONE INVOLVED IN THIS.
>>Gregg: IT IS A DIVISION OF
AUTISM OPPOSED TO A SEPARATE
DIAGNOSIS CATEGORY.
WE WILL HAVE TO LEAVE IT THERE
BECAUSE WE ARE OUT OF TIME.
DOCTOR, THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR
THIS TOUGH TOPIC.
THAT DOES IT FOR US.
LET BEAR IS UP NEXT AS WE
CONTINUE OUR SPECIAL COVERAGE OF
THE HORRIFIC EVENT FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
CAN CAUSE CRAMPS.
BUT Phillips' Caplets
DON'T.
THEY HAVE MAGNESIUM.
FOR EFFECTIVE RELIEF
OF OCCASIONAL CONSTIPATION.
THANKS.
[ Phillips' Lady ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
TILL YOU FINISH YOUR VEGETABLES.
[ clock ticking ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THERE'S A BETTER WAY...
V8 V-FUSION.
VEGETABLE NUTRITION THEY NEED,
FRUIT TASTE THEY LOVE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
OR...TRY KIDS BOXES!
morning because my back
hurt so bad.
The Sleep Number bed
conforms to you.
I wake up in the morning
with no back pain.
I can adjust it if I need
to...if my back's a little
more sore.
And by the time I get up
in the morning, I feel great!
If you have back pain,
toss and turn at night or
wake up tired with no
energy, the Sleep Number
bed could be your
solution.
The Sleep Number bed's
secret is it's air
chambers which provide
ideal support and put you
in control of the
firmness.
And the bed is perfect for
couples because each side
adjusts independently to
their unique Sleep Number.
Here's what clinical
research has found: ® 93%
of participants
experienced back-pain relief.
® 90% reported reduced
aches and pains.
® 87% fell asleep faster
and enjoyed more deep sleep.
For study summaries, call
this number now.
We'll include a Free DVD
and brochure about the
Sleep Number bed including
prices, and models plus a
FREE $50 savings Card.
And how about this?
Steel springs can cause
uncomfortable pressure points.
But the Sleep Number bed
contours to your body.
Imagine how good you'll
feel when your muscles
relax and you fall into a
deep sleep!
I'm not just a back surgeon, I'm
also a back patient.
I sleep on the Sleep
Number bed myself and I
highly recommend it to all
of my patients.
Need another reason to
call?
The Sleep Number bed costs
about the same as an
innerspring but lasts
twice as long.
So if you want to sleep
better or find relief for
your bad back, call now.
Call the number on your
screen for your free