DETECTO
DETECTORS, AND GUARDS.
>> AND THESE KIDS HAVE HATRED.
>> BEYOND THAT DAY IN 1999
DEANGELUS WILL BE HAUNTED BY
THE RECENT WORDS OF A FBI
PROFILING.
>> FRANK I CAN ASSURE YOU
THERE'S SOMEONE RIGHT NOW
PLANNING SOMETHING NOR BIGGER
AND DEVASTATING THAN WHAT
HAPPENED AT COLUMBINE HIGH
SCHOOL AND SADLY ENOUGH, HE'S
RIGHT.
THERE WAS A 20 MINUTES TIME
SPAN WHEN I SAW THE TWO LITTLE
GIRLS AND SAW MY SISTER AND
THOSE WERE THE WORST 20
MINUTES OF MY LIFE AND I CAN'T
PUT IT INTO WORDS.
>> A TOWN AND A NATION REELING
FROM THE HEART BREAKING
SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
A LONG AND INTENSE
INVESTIGATION IS UNDERWAY,
SEARCHING FOR ANSWERS WHAT
WOULD CAUSE SOMEONE TO SHOOT
UP A SCHOOL KILLING 26 PEOPLE,
SO MANY OF THEM CHILDREN.
>> AND JUST THIS MORNING,
AUTHORITIES ARE SAYING THAT
GUNMAN ADAM LANZA WASN'T
VOLUNTARILY LET INSIDE THE
SCHOOL, BUT RATHER, HE FORCED
HIS WAY ARMED WITH MULTIPLE
WEAPONS AND NOW TOWN OFFICIALS
ARE SAYING THE PRINCIPAL WAS
KILLED TRYING TO STOP LANZA
AND SAYING THEY HAVE QUOTE,
GOOD EVIDENCE IN THIS CASE.
HELLO, I'M UMA PEMMARAJU.
>> Kelly: AND I'M KELLY WRIGHT
AND WE BEGIN A SPECIAL EDITION
OF AMERICA'S NEWS HEADQUARTERS
WHICH BEGINS RIGHT NOW AND
WE'LL GO RIGHT TO NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
STATE POLICE THERE WRAPPING UP
A PRESS CONFERENCE JUST A
SHORT TIME AGO.
OUR MOLLY LINE IS STANDING BY
LIVE NEAR SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WITH THE
LATEST ON THE INVESTIGATION,
MOLLY.
>> THERE'S A BROAD EXPECTATION
OF GRIEF AND AT SOME POINT THE
NAMES OF VICTIMS WILL BE
RELEASED TODAY.
WE DO KNOW THAT ALL OF THE
VICTIMS' BODIES HAVE BEEN
IDENTIFIED AND REMOVED FROM
THE SCHOOL AND OFFERING
COMFORT THROUGHOUT THE DAY AS
WELL.
YOU MENTIONED THAT POLICE HAVE
SAID THAT THIS THE SHOOTER DID
NOT -- WAS NOT BUZZED INTO THE
BUILDING WILLINGLY AND IN
OTHER WORDS, FORCED HIS WAY IN
AND QUICK TO SAY IN REGARDS TO
BROKEN WINDOWS ACROSS THE
SCHOOL.
THAT MAY HAVE BEEN DONE BY THE
LAW ENFORCEMENT COMMUNITY AND
PEOPLE THAT ARRIVED THERE AND
WANTED TO GET INTO THE SCHOOL
AS QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE TO
RESPOND TO THE EMERGENCY
UNDERWAY AND MEANWHILE,
INVESTIGATORS ARE PEELING BACK
AN ONION HERE, LOOKING AT THE
LAYERS OF THIS AND EVERY
CREVASSE OF THE SCHOOL TO GET
ALL THE INFORMATION THEY NEED
TO FIND OUT WHY THIS HAPPENED.
FEDERAL AUTHORITIES, OUR
SOURCES TOLD US, THE SHOOTER
MAY HAVE HAD ASPERGER'S
SYNDROME AND MENTAL CHALLENGES
THROUGH HIS LIFE AND WHETHER
OR NOT THAT CONTRIBUTED TO THE
SHOOTING, POLICE SAY GOOD
EVIDENCE, NOT DETAILS OF WHAT
THEY HAVE, BUT SOME SORT OF
EVIDENCE TO HELP EXPLAIN THE
HOW AND WHY THIS OCCURRED.
HERE IS A LITTLE BIT FROM
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE AS TO
HOW THE SHOOTER MAY HAVE
GOTTEN INTO THE BUILDING.
>> WE HAVE ESTABLISHED THE
POINT OF ENTRY.
IT WAS, I CAN TELL YOU IT'S
BELIEVED HE WAS NOT
VOLUNTARILY LET INTO THE
SCHOOL AT ALL.
THAT HE FORCED HIS WAY INTO
THE SCHOOL.
>> Reporter:  AND THERE IS
SOME EVIDENCE, REPORTS OUT
THAT LANZA MAY HAVE HAD SOME
SORT OF ALTERCATION AT THE
SCHOOL IN THE DAYS BEFORE THE
SHOOTING OCCURRED.
WE SPOKE WITH LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE AND HE HAS NOT CONFIRMED
SO WE DON'T HAVE ANY KNOWLEDGE
FOR CERTAIN THAT LANZA HAD
BEEN IN THE SCHOOL DAYS BEFORE
THE SHOOTING, BUT ALL OF THESE
THINGS ARE LOOKED INTO AND
AUTHORITIES ARE WORKING TO
FIND EVERYTHING OUT.
>> ONE PERSON THAT MIGHT BE
ABLE TO SHED LIGHT ON WHAT MAY
HAVE HAPPENED DURING THE
COURSE OF THIS MASSACRE, ONE
SURVIVOR, A FEMALE SURVIVOR, A
WOMAN, POLICE SAY THEY'RE
SPEAKING WITH HER AND THAT
WHAT SHE'S SAYING WILL BE
INVOLUMABLE TO FIGURE OUT WHAT
HAPPENED INSIDE THE WALLS OF
THE SCHOOL.
>> THEY'RE WAITING TO HEAR
MORE FROM HER.
MOLLY LINE WITH MORE FROM THE
SCENE, SANDY HOOK SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
UMA.
>> NEW DETAILS ARE EMERGING
ABOUT THE SHOOTER, 20-YEAR-OLD
ADAM LANZA, BUT MANY SPECIFICS
ABOUT HIS MOTIVE REMAIN
UNCLEAR.
HE LIVED WITH HIS MOTHER NANCY
IN A PROSPEROUS AREA OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT AND
CONFIRMED THAT A WOMAN WAS
FOUND DEAD IN THAT HOME AND IT
IS BELIEVED TO BE HIS MOTHER.
THE GUNS FOUND AT THE SCENE
WERE REGISTERED NANCY LANZA
AND RYAN LANZA INITIALLY
IDENTIFIED, SAYS ADAM WAS
AUTISTIC.
AND NEIGHBORS ARE ALSO
REMEMBERING ADAM AS QUOTE,
SENATOR A
SMART, AND ON THE HONOR ROLL.
THEY'VE FOUND NO NOTE FROM THE
TERRIFIC TRAGEDY AND ADAM
WEARING BLACK FATIGUES FORCED
HIS WAY IN AND BEGAN HIS
BLOODY RAMPAGE.
>> Kelly: CONNECTICUT POLICE
RELEASED TAPES OF THE CALLS
THAT CAME IN.
>> AND CALLER INDICATES SHE
THINKS THERE'S SOMEONE
SHOOTING IN A CAR
>>  YOU CAN JUST IMAGINE WHAT
THE POLICE WERE ENCOUNTERING
AS THEY CAME UPON THAT
HORRIBLE TRAGEDY THAT NO ONE
COULD IMAGINE.
DURING THE MORNING'S PRESS
CONFERENCE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY, POLICE SAID THE
SUPERINTENDENT OF SCHOOLS
SHOULD BE ABLE TO PROVIDE MORE
CLARITY ABOUT THE POSSIBLE
MOTIVE.
WE KNOW SHE'S HEADED TO THE
SCENE AND EXPECTED TO HEAR
FROM HER SOMETIME SOON TODAY
AND DURING WHAT IS CALLED AN
ACTIVE SHOOTER SITUATION,
WHICH IS WHAT WE SAW UNFOLD IN
CONNECTICUT, RESPONSE FROM LAW
OFFICIALS IS CRITICAL AT THIS
HOUR.
SO, HOW DO THESE TEAMS RESPOND
WITHOUT PUTTING MORE PEOPLE IN
HARM'S WAY.
WE'RE JOINED NOW BY DAVID
CASS, CHIEF EXECUTIVE AND A
FORMER SPECIAL AGENT TO THE
DRUG ENFORCEMENT AGENCY.
DAVID, WELCOME, THANK YOU FOR
JOINING ON THIS DAY.
OBVIOUSLY WE WISH IT WAS UNDER
BETTER CIRCUMSTANCES.
BUT BACK TO THE POINT.
HAVE YOU EVER EXPERIENCED AN
ACTIVE SHOOTER SITUATION LIKE
THIS ONE WITH POSSIBLE
CASUALTIES AND HOSTAGES
INSIDE?
>> I WAS A SPECIAL AGENT WITH
DRUG ENFORCEMENT, AND ALTHOUGH
THERE ARE HIGH RISK WARRANTS
AND AFFECTING ARREST OF
DANGEROUS PEOPLE THEY'RE
PROACTIVE IN NATURE NOT
REACTIVE.
SO OUR TRAINING FOR THIS TYPE
OF SCENARIO STEMS ON WHAT IS
CALLED THE RESCUE, AN
UNDERCOVER AGENT IN THE
RESIDENCE, IN THE LOCATION
THAT WE HAVE TO GET OUT
QUICKLY.
SO WE WOULD GO IN HEEDLESS,
THE TACTICS LESS DESIGNED TO
MOVE SAFE AND SLOW, BUT
DESIGNED TO GET TO THE PERSON
IN DANGER AS QUICKLY AS
POSSIBLE AND THAT'S WHAT AN
ACTIVE SHOOTER RESPONSE IS ALL
ABOUT.
>> Kelly: SO THAT'S WHAT
YOU'RE TRAINED TO DO.
FROM AN OFFICER-AGENT POINT OF
VIEW WHAT DO YOU EXPECT IN A
SITUATION LIKE THIS, WHEN
SOMEWHAT IS GOING ON INVOLVING
INCIDENT CHILDREN AND TEACHERS
THAT CAN'T DEFEND THEMSELVES.
WHAT'S GOING ON IN YOUR MIND
AND YOUR HEAD IN TERMS OF
REACTION.
>> I THINK I CAN SPEAK FOR
MOST PEOPLE IN LAW
ENFORCEMENT, GET IN AS QUICKLY
AS POSSIBLE AB STOP WHAT'S
HAPPENING IMMEDIATELY AND I
DON'T THINK YOU'RE REALLY
CONCERNED ABOUT--
IN THE BACK OF YOUR MIND, YOU
UNDERSTAND THAT IT'S DANGEROUS
AND IT MAY BE A DANGER TO YOUR
PERSONAL SAFETY, BUT LOOK,
THESE ARE KIDS, ALL OUR
CHILDREN AND THE PARENTS WOULD
HAVE RUSHED IN BARE HANDED TO
CONFRONT THIS AND LAW
ENFORCEMENT, SAT THING.
>> Kelly: YOU'RE RIGHT.
PARENTS WOULD RUN IN BARE
HANDED AND MANY PARENTS IN THE
WAKE OF THE TRAGEDY WITHOUT
THEIR LOVED ONES THERE, FEEL
POWERLESS AND HELPLESS TO DO
ANYTHING.
HOW DO YOU FOLLOW UP ON A
CRIME SCENE LIKE THIS, NOT
ONLY IN TERMS OF THE FAMILY
AND BRIEG THEM SAL LAST, BUT
GATHERING ALL THE NECESSARY
EVIDENCE THAT WILL HELP THEM
UNDERSTAND WHAT POSSIBLY WENT
WRONG AND WHY IT HAPPENED.
>> AND AT THIS POINT, IT'S NOT
A MATTER OF GATHERING EVIDENCE
FOR A TRIAL, A TRIAL, RATHER,
BUT THE SHOOTER IS DEAD.
JUST IN THE OFF, OFF CHANCE
THERE IS ANOTHER INVOLVED
PERSON, WHICH IS VERY, VERY
UNLIKELY AND YOU WANT TO MAKE
SURE THAT YOU DO THE
INVESTIGATION THOROUGHLY AND
IT'S ABSOLUTELY HEART BREAKING
WHEN YOU HEAR THAT THE
CHILDREN WERE LYING AT SCHOOL
FOR ALL THOSE HOURS AND
NOTHING YOU CAN DO ABOUT IT,
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER HAS TO
TAKE THE NECESSARY STEPS AND
OF COURSE THE CRIME SCENE HAS
TO BE WELL DOCUMENTED AND
PRESERVED.
BUT THE ONLY THING YOU CAN DO
IS HOPE THAT THERE ARE LESSONS
LEARNED AND GOING FORWARD,
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS ARE
PREVENTED.
>> AND BEFORE YOU LET YOU GO,
WHAT ARE YOUR CONCERNS OF
SOMEONE LIKE THIS GAINING
ACCESS TO SUCH HIGH CALIBER
WEAPONS, ANYTHING THAT COULD
HAVE BEEN DONE TO PREVENT THE
GUY FROM GETTING HOLD OF THE
WEAPONS AND USING THEM IN SUCH
A MANNER AS THIS WAS TOTALLY
UNAPPROPRIATE, INAPPROPRIATE?
>> WELL, THE REPORTS, WEAPONS
WERE REGISTERED TO THE MOTHER
AND I CANNOT EMPHASIZE ENOUGH,
OWNING A FIREARM IS A
TREMENDOUS RESPONSIBILITY AND
SECURING THEM FROM SOMEONE NOT
TO HAVE ACCESS TO THEM.
YOU FILL OUT A QUESTIONNAIRE
AND REQUIRED BY FEDERAL LAW,
AND ONE IS AN EXHAUSTIVE
CRIMINAL BACKGROUND AND UNDER
INDICTMENT AND LINE ITEMS
WHETHER YOU'RE TREATED FOR
MENTAL ILLNESS OR ON NARCOTICS
OR MEDICATIONS AND NO WAY FOR
PEOPLE INVOLVED IN SELLING
WEAPONS TO VERIFY, AND DO A
CRIMINAL BACKGROUND CHECK,
WHICH IS DONE, BUT THE MENTAL
ISSUE WE NEED TO DO A BETTER
JOB OF IDENTIFYING THESE
PEOPLE AND MAKING IT
IMPOSSIBLE FOR THEM TO GET A
HOLD OF WEAPONS.
>> Kelly: THAT CERTAINLY SEEMS
TO BE A QUESTION A LOT OF
PEOPLE ARE LOOKING AT WHEN
THEY MOVE FORWARD WITH THIS
INVESTIGATION AND REACTION TO
THIS.
WE THANK YOU VERY MUCH, SIR.
>> AND HOW THIS, AND TWO THEY
TOOK TO THE HOSPITAL ARE DEAD
NOW AND YOU CAN PRETTY MUCH
ASSUME THAT THE ONES IN THE
HOSPITAL, I MEAN, THAT ARE IN
THE SCHOOL ARE DEAD.
AND EVERYBODY IN THE SCHOOL IS
DEAD.
>> THIS TOWN IS 300 YEARS OLD.
THIS IS PROBABLY THE WORST DAY
IN THE HISTORY OF THIS TOWN.
AND IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE THAT
ANYTHING LIKE THIS COULD
HAPPEN IN THIS TOWN, IT'S A
QUIET TOWN, MAYBE IT'S TOO
QUIET.
>> LOT OF EMOTION AND LOTS OF
PAIN THERE.
AND UNDERSTANDABLY NEWTON'S
RESIDENTS REMAIN IN SHOCK AS
THEIR BUCOLIC LITTLE TOWN WAS
HIT WITH ONE OF THE DEADLIEST
MASS SHOOTING.
AND WHAT'S LEFT OF THE 30,000
WHO LIVE IN THAT COMMUNITY
WITH A VERY LOW CRIME RATE.
HARD TO IMAGINE BACK IN 2010,
NEWTOWN SAW ONLY ONE VIOLENT
CRIME.
WELL, YOUR CHILD DIDN'T HAVE
TO BE, BUT WATCHING ON
TELEVISION CAN BE TRAUMATIZING
AS WELL.
HOW COULD WE EXPLAIN WHAT IS
HAPPENING TO OUR CHILDREN.
AND FROM HARVARD MEDICAL
SCHOOL, JOINING VALUABLE
INSIGHT AND OFFERING WAYS OF
COMFORT AND HOPE AS MANY ARE
STRUGGLING TO FIND THIS
SENSELESS TRAGEDY.
GOOD TO HAVE YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> IF YOUR CHILD SAYS I'M
SCARED.
ISN'T THE WORST THING TO SAY
THAT YOU SHOULDN'T BE SCARED.
SHOULDN'T WE ACKNOWLEDGE THEIR
FEELINGS.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
THE FIRST THING WE SHOULD DO
IS LISTEN TO THE CHILDREN
REACT TO THEIR FEAR AND GRIEF,
BEING SCARED AND ANXIOUS AND
BEING DEPRESSED AND WANTING TO
BE COMFORTED AND HUGGED,
THAT'S ALSO VERY IMPORTANT AND
FOR THE PARENTS TO KIND OF
STAND BY AND A LOT OF THOSE
CHILDREN, AND CHILDREN AROUND
THE COUNTRY, BECAUSE OF WHAT
HAPPENED IN CONNECTICUT, ARE
GOING TO BE HAVING NIGHTMARES
TONIGHT, SLEEP PROBLEMS, MAYBE
EATING PROBLEMS, MAYBE A LOT
OF PHYSICAL COMPLAINTS,
STOMACH ACHES, UPSETS.
I THINK THAT PARENTS HAVE TO
BE VERY ALERT TO THAT AND KNOW
THAT THEY HAVE TO BE
REASSURING TO THE CHILDREN AS
MUCH AS POSSIBLE.
MANY OF THEM AROUND THE
COUNTRY, NOT JUST AGAIN IN
CONNECTICUT, ARE NOT GOING TO
WANT TO GO TO SCHOOL ON
MONDAY, PERHAPS.
BECAUSE THEY DON'T FEEL SAFE.
THEY'RE THE NOT CLEAR WHY THIS
HAPPENED AND WHETHER IT COULD
HAPPEN IN THEIR SCHOOL AS WELL
SO THEY ARE HE' GOING TO HAVE
SOME ANXIETY AND PARENTS MAY
HAVE TO SUPPORT THEM AND
REASSURE THEM THAT THEY'RE
SAFE IN THEIR SCHOOL.
NOW, RIGHT NOW, PEOPLE ARE NOT
FEELING THAT WAY, BUT PUTTING
IT IN PERSPECTIVE, THESE ARE
CURRENCIES, RELATIVELY RARE.
IF YOU LOOK AT THEM.
SO, IT HAPPENED.
IT'S AWFUL, IT'S TRAGIC, IT'S
PAINFUL PARTICULARLY FOR THE
CONNECTICUT PEOPLE WHERE THIS
IS GOING TO BE WITH THEM OR
THE REST OF THEIR LIVES, BUT I
THINK THAT WE SHOULD LET THE
OTHER CHILDREN IN THE COUNTRY
KNOW THAT THEY'RE RELATIVELY
SAFE AND THAT THE PARENTS WILL
PROTECT THEM, THE SCHOOLING
WILL DO ALL THAT THEY CAN TO
PROTECT THEM.
THE POLICE WILL DO ALL THAT
THEY CAN TO PROTECT THEM.
AND SO FAR, LOOKING AT IT IN
THE LONG-TERM, IT HAS BEEN
WORKING WELL, BUT WE STILL ARE
SCARRED BY THESE AWFUL,
HORRIFIC TRAGEDIES THAT DAMAGE
NOT ONLY THE COMMUNITIES AND
THE CHILDREN, BUT ALSO THE HE
BE TIRE COUNTRY.
>> INDEED.
YOU'VE DONE SOME GROUND
BREAKING WORK WITH YOUNG
PEOPLE, PARTICULARLY WHEN IT
COMES OF ISSUE OF VIOLENCE.
HOW DO YOU ENGAGE TEENAGERS,
FOR EXAMPLE, IN THESE
CONVERSATIONS?
>> WELL, I THINK THAT
TEENAGERS PRETTY MUCH HAVE A
REGULAR DISCUSSION ABOUT THE
VIOLENCE.
THEY'RE GOING TO BE AS PUZZLED
AS ADULTS.
BUT I THINK WE ALSO IS TO
EXPLAIN TO TEENAGERS AND
CHILDREN THAT WE HAVE TO DO
ALL THAT WE CAN TO PREVENT
VIOLENCE.
YOU KNOW, SINCE THESE
SHOOTINGS STARTING, DECADES
AGO, THAT WE HAVE VIOLENCE
PREVENTION PROGRAMS, CONFLICT
RESOLUTION PROGRAMS, WE HAVE
PROGRAMS THAT TEACH CHILDREN
TOLERANCE, ANTI-BULLYING
PROGRAMS SO THAT YOUNG PEOPLE
DON'T DEVELOP THE KIND OF HATE
AND FURY AND FRUSTRATION THAT
LEADS SOMEONE TO COMMIT A
CRIME AS HORRIFIC AS THIS ONE.
SO I THINK WE STILL SHOULD
FOCUS ON OUR VIOLENCE
PREVENTION EFFORTS AND I THINK
THE WHOLE ISSUE OF GUN CONTROL
SHOULD COME UP.
PARENTS SHOULD PARTICIPATE IN
THAT.
OTHER CITIZENS.
WHAT KIND OF CONTROLS DO WE
NEED THAT MIGHT MINIMIZE THE
CHANCES OF SOMETHING LIKE THIS
OCCURRING.
AND I THINK THAT THINGS WE CAN
DO.
REICH RIGHT NOW, WE HAVE CLOSE
TO 300 MILLION GUNS IN
CIRCULATION AND HANDS AND
THAT'S ONE GUN FOR EVERY MAN,
WOMAN AND CHILD IN THE
IF YOU HAVE THAT MANY GUNS IN
CIRCULATION, YOU CAN BE SURE
THERE ARE GOING TO BE PEOPLE,
WE DON'T HAVE TO TALK ABOUT
MOTIVATION, WE TALK ABOUT THE
FACT THERE ARE A CERTAIN
NUMBER OF DERANGED PEOPLE, I'M
NOT SAYING MENTALLY ILL,
BECAUSE THAT'S KIND OF
CONTROVERSIAL ISSUE, BUT THEY
CERTAINLY ARE DERANGED PEOPLE
WHO WILL DO SOMETHING LIKE
THIS, THAT IN MY DEFINITION,
THESE PEOPLE ARE SUFFERING
FROM MENTAL DISORDERS OF
VARIOUS TYPES BEING EXPRESSED
IN DIFFERENT WAYS.
AND SO I THINK--
YES, GO AHEAD.
>> DO YOU THINK THAT YOUNG
PEOPLE MAY HAVE A TENDENCY TO
BECOME IMMUNE OF THE VIOLENCE
IF NE CONTINUE TO SEE THE
STORIES WE'VE SEEN OVER THE
LAST SEVERAL MONTHS OF ONE
SHOOTING AFTER ANOTHER?
>> WELL, YES, I CAN.
IN FACT, ONE OF THE THINGS
THAT WE KNOW WHEN CHILDREN
WATCH A LOT OF VIOLENCE ON
TELEVISION AND THE MOVIES, AND
EVEN IN VIDEO GAMES, THEY
BECOME A BIT NUMB TO IT ALL.
AS IF IT'S NOT REALLY
HAPPENING, AS IF THEY REALLY
DON'T APPRECIATE WHAT DEATH
AND KILLING IS.
YES, THAT CAN HAPPEN AND EVEN
YESTERDAY, COME SOME OF THE
KIDS WERE ACTING NUMBER TO THE
VIOLENCE AND CHILDREN WERE
SEEING VIOLENCE NEARLY EVERY
DAY ON THE SIX O'CLOCK NEWS
SWELLS IN VIDEO GAMES AS WELL
AS ON TELEVISION AND THE
MOVIES AND SO IT'S LIKE AN
EVERYDAY KIND OF MATTER AND
THE YOUNGER ONES AREN'T SURE
WHEN PEOPLE ARE KILLED THAT
THEY'RE DEAD.
SO, WE HAVE TO -- WE HAVE TO
CONTINUE THE DISCUSSION AND
MAKE IT A POSITIVE ONE TO TRY
TO DO SOMETHING ABOUT THESE
HORRIFIC EVENTS.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
IT'S GREAT TO HAVE YOU HERE
TODAY.
THANK YOU FOR SHARING YOUR
INSIGHT.
WE'RE GRATEFUL FOR HAVING YOU
ON TODAY AND OF COURSE, THIS
IS SOMETHING WE'RE GOING TO BE
TALKING ABOUT FOR SOME TIME,
APPRECIATE IT.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Kelly: BREAKING NEWS FROM
WASHINGTON, A STATE DEPARTMENT
SPOKESMAN SAYS THAT HILLARY
CLINTON IS RECOVERING AFTER
SUSTAINING A CONCUSSION.
CHIEF WASHINGTON CORRESPONDENT
JAMES ROSEN IS LIVE IN
WASHINGTON WITH THE LATEST
DETAILS ABOUT IT.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT
SENATOR--
I SHOULD SAY SECRETARY
CLINTON'S CONDITION?
>> SECRETARY OF STATE CLINTON
HAD CANCELED AN OVERSEAS TRIP
THAT WAS TO TAKE HER TO NORTH
AFRICA AND THE MIDEAST DUE TO
THE ILLNESS THAT LED TO HER
INJURY THIS WEEK.
CLINTON HAS BEEN SUFFERING
FROM WHAT AIDES HAVE BEEN
DESCRIBING AS A VICIOUS CAN
STOMACH VIRUS.
AND THE CANCELLATION OF THE
TRIP IS UNUSUAL FOR THE
65-YEAR-OLD, LOGGED MORE MILES
THAN ANY OTHER SECRETARY OF
STATE.
AND THE DEPUTY SECRETARY OF
STATE SAID IN A STATEMENT
TODAY AND I QUOTE, WHILE
SUFFERING FROM A STOMACH
VIRUS, SHE BECAME DEHYDRATED
AND SUSTAINED A CONCUSSION,
SHE'S RECOVERING AT HOME AND
WILL CONTINUE TO BE MONITORED
REGULARLY.
AND SHE'LL BE WORKING FROM
HOME AND STAYING IN CONTACT
WITH DEPARTMENT AND OTHER
OFFICIALS AND LOOKING FORWARD
TO BEING BACK IN THE OFFICE
SOON.
EARLIER THIS WEEK, REPORTERS
AT THE STATE DEPARTMENT PRESS
BRIEFING CAUTIONED DEPARTMENTS
SPOKESWOMAN VICTORIA NEWLANDS
AROUND THE WORLD WHEN SHE
MENTIONED OFFHANDEDLY THAT THE
SECRETARY WAS QUOTE, REALLY,
VERY ILL.
>> SHE'S GOT A -- A VERY
UNCOMFORTABLE STOMACH VIRUS.
ANY OF YOU EVER HAD A STOMACH
VIRUS KNOWS THAT THAT IS NOT
COMFORTABLE.
>>, BUT IT'S NOT LIFE
THREATENING.
>> IT IS NOT, IT IS NOT.
IT IS NOT, IT IS NOT.
>> AND TALKING TO PEOPLE,
RIGHT?
>> SHE IS--
HAS NOT BEEN WORKING, SHE'S
BEEN TRYING TO RECOVER.
>> AND WE ALSO KNOW NOW FROM
THE STATEMENT THAT SECRETARY
CLINTON'S GOING TO BE STAYING
AT HOME THIS NEXT WEEK.
THAT MEANS SHE WILL NOT, AS
EXPECTED, BE TESTIFYING ON
CAPITOL HILL ABOUT THE EVENTS
IN BENGHAZI.
SO FOR SECRETARY CLINTON'S
ACCOUNT OF THE EVENTS AB AS
SHE PERCEIVED THEM IN
WASHINGTON.
WE WILL HAVE TO WAIT LONGER.
>> I THINK MEMBERS CAN WAIT
CONSIDERING HER ILLNESS AND
HOPE BACK TO TIP TOP SHAPE
SOON.
>> WE HOPE SO.
>> OF THE NATION GRIEVES
INCLUDING A VISIBLY UPSET
PRESIDENT OBAMA.
WHAT IS THE PRESIDENT CALLING
FOR IN THE WAKE OF THE
SHOOTING?
>> THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM, BIRTHDAYS,
GRADUATIONS, WEDDINGS, KIDS
ARE GONE.
>> AND AN INCIDENT LIKE THIS
COULD TEST ONE'S FAITH.
WE'LL HEAR FROM THE MONSIGNOR
PROVIDING SUPPORT AND COMFORT
TO THE RESIDENTS OF NEWTOWN.
ENERGY IS BEING PRODUCED
TO POWER OUR LIVES.
WHILE ENERGY DEVELOPMENT
COMES WITH SOME RISK,
NORTH AMERICA'S NATURAL GAS
PRODUCERS ARE COMMITTED
TO SAFELY AND RESPONSIBLY
PROVIDING GENERATIONS
OF CLEANER-BURNING ENERGY
FOR OUR COUNTRY,
DRILLING THOUSANDS OF FEET
BELOW FRESH WATER SOURCES
WITHIN SELF-CONTAINED
WELL SYSTEMS.
AND, USING STATE-OF-THE-ART
MONITORING TECHNOLOGIES,
RIGOROUS PRACTICES HELP ENSURE
OUR OPERATIONS
ARE SAFE AND CLEAN
FOR OUR COMMUNITIES
AND THE ENVIRONMENT.
WE'RE AMERICA'S NATURAL GAS.
I HAD[ Designer ]EELING
ENOUGH OF JUST COVERING UP
MY MODERATE TO SEVERE
PLAQUE PSORIASIS.
I DECIDED ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
♪
[ Spa Lady ]
I STARTED ENBREL.
IT'S CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO PROVIDE CLEARER SKIN.
[ RV Guy ] ENBREL MAY NOT WORK
FOR EVERYONE --
AND MAY NOT CLEAR YOU
COMPLETELY,
BUT FOR MANY, IT GETS SKIN
CLEARER FAST, WITHIN 2 MONTHS,
AND KEEPS IT CLEARER
UP TO 9 MONTHS.
[ Male Announcer ]
BECAUSE ENBREL®, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL,
EVENTS INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS, LYMPHOMA,
OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING ENBREL,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START ENBREL IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON ENBREL, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING,
OR PALENESS.
IF YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH, ASK
YOUR DERMATOLOGIST ABOUT ENBREL.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with uimited
talk and text.
by HTC for $49.99.
ICHLTD.
>> Uma: WELCOME BACK
EVERYBODY, 18 FOURTH GRADERS
HID IN THE STORAGE ROOM OF THE
LIBRARY DURING THE HORRIFIC
SHOOTING.
THE LIBRARIAN AND ASSISTANT
LOCKED AND BARRICADED THE
DOOR.
AND THEY HAD THE CHILDREN
COLOR WHILE THEY WAITED FOR
THE SHOOTING TO END.
THE TEACHERS ARE SCARED EVEN
WITH A DRILL.
A SCARY THING.
WHEN THE FIRE ALARM GOES OFF,
YOUR ADRENALIN AND IT'S SCARY
FOR KIDS.
>> AND BRAVE WOMAN THERE.
THEY WAITED FOR THE OFFICER TO
SLIDE THE BADGE UNDER THE THE
DOOR TO MAKE SURE THE OFFICERS
WERE TELLING THE TRUTH.
>> THEY KNOW THAT THE TOWN OF
NEWTOWN IS A SMALL COMMUNITY
AND REMEMBER THE LIVES THAT
WERE LOST AND THEY TRY TO FIND
COMFORT IN FAITH AND IN GOD.
FOR THAT PART OF THE STORY
THOUGH, WE GO NOW TO FOX NEWS
ANALYST PETER JOHNSON, JR. WHO
HAS MORE DETAILS ABOUT THIS.
PETER, TELL US MORE, PLEASE.
>> KELLY, I WAS EARLY THIS
MORNING IN AT THAT TOWN,
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT AND AS
YOU COULD PUNCH A TOWN IN THE
COLLECTIVE STOMACH THAT
HAPPENED IN NEWTOWN, NEVER SAW
SO MANY DISCONSULATE,
DISSPIRITED, PEOPLE CRYING IN
THE GENERAL STORE AND IN
CHURCH THIS MORNING.
I HAD AN OPPORTUNITY TO, EARLY
THIS MORNING, SPEAK WITH
MONSIGNOR ROBERT WEISS OF THE
SAINT ROSA LIMA PARISH THERE.
SIX CHILDREN DIED FROM THAT
PARISH AND PROVIDES
CONSOLATION NOT ONLY FOR THEM,
BUT FOR US AS AMERICANS.
>> HE SAID TO ME, YOU KNOW, I
DON'T HAVE ANYBODY TO PLAY
WITH ANYMORE, I'VE LOST MY
BEST FRIEND AND I SAID TO HIM
THAT GOD IS GOING TO SEND YOU
SOME COMFORTABLE NEW FRIENDS,
YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE AFRAID
AND YOU'LL ALWAYS HAVE YOUR
SISTER IN YOUR HEART.
AND I SAID TO HIM, YOU DON'T
HAVE TO WORRY BECAUSE SHE'S
VERY SAFE BECAUSE SHE'S WITH
GOD AND WE TALKED A LITTLE BIT
WHAT HAPPENED AND HE REALIZED
THAT SHE WAS GOING TO BE HAPPY
AND SAFE, BUT IT WAS SHORTLY
AFTER THAT HE BROKE DOWN INTO
TEA
TEARS.
>> Reporter:  MONSIGNOR WEISS
HAD TO EXPLAIN TO A LITTLE BOY
THAT HIS SISTER HAD GONE TO
HEAVEN AND HE'S PART OF THE
CLERGY IN THAT TOWN THAT ARE
KEEPING PEOPLE TOGETHER.
THEY ARE HE' SCARED, THEY'RE
AFRAID.
IN FACT, ONE MAN CAME UP TO ME
THIS MORNING, PLEASE, SAINT TO
THE SATELLITE TRUCKS AND
REPORTERS, PLEASE DON'T HURT
OUR TOWN.
I SAID I'M FROM FOX NEWS, I
CAME HERE TO SHARE AND GRIEVE
AND BE IN SOLIDARITY AND I
LOST MY OWN FATHER THIS WEEK
HE HAD A LONG, LONG LIFE, BUT
WE UNDERSTAND LOSS IN THIS
COUNTRIES AND WE UNDERSTAND
THE NEED TO PULL TOGETHER AND
BE TOGETHER AND THAT'S WHAT
THE MONSIGNOR WAS TALKING
ABOUT THIS MORNING, THE NEED
TO BE PRESENT, AND SHARE GOD'S
MERCY AND UNDERSTAND THAT
FAITH WILL IN FACT BRING US
THROUGH THIS.
HE SAID, VERY INTERESTINGLY,
YOU KNOW, PEOPLE QUESTION
WHETHER THIS HAS SHAKEN BY
FAITH IN GOD.
NO, IT HASN'T.
IT MAY HAVE SHAKEN MY FAITH IN
HUMAN BEINGS AS TO WHAT I'VE
SOON THE LAST 25, 30 YEARS IN
THIS COUNTRY, BUT NOT MY FAITH
IN GOD.
>> A LOT OF PEOPLE WOULD AGREE
WITH HIM ON THAT AND THE
MONSIGNOR HAS SO MANY THINGS
TO DO, THOSE SIX CHILDREN WENT
TO HIS PARISH.
HE WILL HAVE TO GO THROUGH THE
PAINFUL TASK OF FUNERALIZING
THEM AND REMINDING PEOPLE THAT
THEY'RE IN GOD'S HANDS AND
SHOW US MORE OF THIS
INTERVIEW, IF YOU CAN, PLEASE.
>> Reporter:  YEAH, LET'S
WATCH SOME MORE RIGHT NOW.
>> YOU KNOW, THAT LIGHT THAT
SHONE OVER CHRIST IS GOING TO
SHINE OVER THESE CHILDREN AS
WELL.
THEY ARE AN ANGELS NOW.
AND I THINK WHEN THEY REFLECT
ON THE CHRIST CHILD BEING
BORN, IT'S A MESSAGE OF HOPE
AND I'M HOPING A MESSAGE THAT
PEOPLE CAN TAKE AWAY TONIGHT.
THERE'S STILL A REASON TO
HOPE, TO HOLD ON AND THESE
FAMILIES OF OTHER CHILDREN
THAT THEY HAVE TO CONTINUE TO
RAISE AND I'M JUST HOPING THAT
THE STRENGTH THAT COMES FROM
THE CHRIST CHILD WILL BE WITH
THESE FAMILIES AND THESE
PARENTS.
>> Reporter:  AND THE
MONSIGNOR AND THE FAMILIES ARE
LIVING THE CREDO WHERE THERE'S
LIFE THERE'S HOPE.
THIS AFTERNOON A LIVE NATIVITY
SCENE.
AND NEAR THE END OF THE 5:30
MAST A MAN WILL COME AND SAY
THERE'S A STAR OVER THE
STABLE.
AND THE CONGREGATION WILL WALK
OVER TO THE STABLE, AND
THERE'S BE REPRESENTING THE
CHRIST CHILD IN THE NATIVITY
SCENE.
AND THOSE WHO LOST LOVED ONES
WILL COME TOGETHER IN A WAY
THAT'S INHERENTLY AMERICAN,
INHERENTLY SPIRITUAL AND
ADOPTING A VERY CHRISTIAN AND
JUDEO-CHRISTI
JUDEO-CHRISTIAN.
>> I KNOW YOU'RE A GREAT
ANCHOR, BUT YOU'VE CONSOLED
PEOPLE IN THEIR TIMES OF NEED
AND YOU UNDERSTAND THE GREAT
FOREIGNS NOT ONLY FOR THAT
COMMUNITY, BUT FOR THE
COUNTRY.
WE LIT CANDLES AND PRAYED IN
THE CHURCH AT 5:30 THIS
MORNING, AND THIS IS A LOT FOR
AMERICA TO SEE THEM TOGETHER.
>> Kelly: OUR PRAYERS ARE WITH
YOU AND YOUR FAMILY.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> Kelly: PETER JOHNSON, A
VERY GOOD FRIEND AND BY THE
WAY, PETER, MY CONDOLENCES TO
THE LOSS OF YOUR FATHER.
>> THANKS, KELLY.
>> Uma: WELL, ACROSS THE
COUNTRY THEY'RE STILL TRYING
TO MAKE SOME SENSE OUT OF
SOMETHING SO HORRIFIC IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE MUCH MORE
ON WHAT WE MUST COMMUNICATE TO
OUR CHILDREN AT A TIME WHEN
EVENTS LIKE THIS TEST OUR
FAITH AND OUR SPIRIT.
WE'RE GOING TO ASK DR. KEITH
ABLOW NEXT.
S
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
SOMETHING MADE YOUR JAW DROP?
CAMPBELL'S HAS 24 NEW SOUPS
THAT WILL MAKE IT DROP OVER,
AND OVER AGAIN.
♪
FROM JAMMIN' JERK CHICKEN,
TO CREAMY GOUDA BISQUE.
SEE WHAT'S NEW FROM CAMPBELL'S.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OURENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
♪
>>  TO BE LOVED OR TO BE
GIVING, TO BE RECEIVED--
>> AS THE NATION TRIES TO FIND
ITS WAY THROUGH THE TRAGEDY,
PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS THE
DIFFICULT TASK AS CONSOLER IN
CHIEF AS HE LEADS A STUNNED
AND GRIEVING NATION.
MOLLY HENNEBERG IS HERE WITH
THE REACTION FROM THE NATION'S
CAPITAL.
>> Reporter:  HI, KELLY.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN TODAY,
THAT'S WHAT PRESIDENT OBAMA
SAID DURING HIS WEEKLY RADIO
ADDRESS AND SAYS THAT THE
NATION GRIEVES FOR THE
FAMILIES WHO LOST LOVED ONES.
>> THIS WEEKENDS, MICHELLE AND
I ARE DOING WHAT I KNOW EVERY
PARENT IS DOING, HOLDING OUR
CHILDREN AS CLOSE AS WE CAN
AND REMINDING THEM HOW MUCH WE
LOVE THEM.
THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CAN'T DO THAT
TODAY AND THEY NEED ALL OF US
RIGHT NOW BECAUSE WHILE
NOTHING CAN TAKE THE PLACE
AFTER LOST CHILD OR A LOVED
ONE, ALL OF US CAN EXTEND A
HAND TO THOSE IN NEED TO
REMIND THEM THAT WE'RE THERE
FOR THEM.
>> THE FLAGS WERE LOWERED TO
HALF STAFF, AT BOTH THE WHITE
HOUSE AND THE CAPITOL IN HONOR
OF THOSE WHO WERE KILLED.
REPUBLICANS IN CONGRESS
USUALLY DO A WEEKLY ADDRESS OF
THEIR OWN ON SATURDAYS, BUT
NOT TODAY.
G.O.P. HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER SAID THERE WOULD BE NO
REPUBLICAN ADDRESS SO THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA COULD SPEAK
FOR THE ENTIRE NATION AT THIS
TIME OF MOURNING.
SPEAKER BOEHNER DID SAY IN A
PAPER STATEMENT, QUOTE, THE
HORROR OF THIS DAY SEEMS SO
UNBEARABLE, BUT WE WILL LOCK
ARMS AND UNITE IN CITIZENS FOR
THOSE HOW AMERICANS RISE ABOVE
UNSPEAKABLE EVIL.
LET US KOCOME TOGETHER IN GOD'S
GRACE FOR THE FAMILIES OF THE
VICTIMS, THAT THEY MAY FIND
SOME COMFORT AND PIECE AMID
SUCH SUFFERING.
AND PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID THE
COUNTRY NEEDS TO TAKE QUOTE,
MEANINGFUL ACTION TO PREVENT
MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS.
KELLY.
>> Kelly: MOLLY HENNEBERG,
THANK YOU FOR THAT REPORT.
>> Uma: WELL, EXPLAINING
VIOLENCE TO YOUR CHILDREN IS
NEVER EASY, AS WE TRY TO WRAP
OUR MURDER AROUND THE MOST
INNOCENT OF VICTIMS.
WE'VE BEEN ASKING THE EXPERTS
HOW BEST TO COMFORT OUR
CHILDREN.
DR. KEITH ABLOW HE IS JOINING
US WITH INSIGHT.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
I WANT TO ASK YOU ABOUT
EFFORTS TO HELP COMFORT OUR
OWN CHILDREN AND HELP THEM
FEEL SAFER, BUT FIRST, WHAT
ABOUT THE CHILDREN WHO
SURVIVED YESTERDAY'S ATTACKS.
HOW DO THOSE PARENTS COMFORT
THEM AT THIS TIME?
>> WHAT THEY NEED TO DO IS BE
VERY, VERY AVAILABLE TO THEM
AND ASK THEM ABOUT THEIR
FEELINGS, DON'T PRESSURE THEM
FOR THOSE FEELINGS, BUT BE
AVAILABLE, MAKE IT PLAIN THAT
THEY CAN TELL THEM ANYTHING,
THAT THERE'S NO LIMIT TO THE
NUMBER OF QUESTIONS OR THE
NATURE OF THOSE QUESTIONS, AND
IF MY CHILD WERE IN THAT
SCHOOL, I WOULD BE IN A
PSYCHOLOGIST OR PSYCHIATRIST'S
OFFICE YESTERDAY BECAUSE I
THINK THESE THINGS ARE REALLY
BETTER ADDRESSED AS A TEAM AND
THE APPROPRIATE TEAM MEMBER IS
MOST OFTEN A MENTAL HEALTH
OFFICIAL OR POTENTIALLY CLERGY
MEMBER, THAT'S WHAT I WOULD DO
FOR MY CHILD, I WOULD START
NOW.
>> Uma: DO EVEN THE YOUNGEST
CHILDREN AS YOUNG AS FIVE OR
SIX, CAN THEY EXPERIENCE
SURVIVORS GUILT?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
FIVE OR SIX YEAR OLDS CAN BE
LEFT WITHOUT ANY EXPLANATION,
AND SO THE SUDDENNESS OF THIS,
THE CRUEL VARABILITIES OF
THIS, HOW COULD THIS HAVE
HAPPENED IN THIS CLASSROOM AND
NOT THAT ONE.
WHY TO MY FRIEND AND NOT
SOMEONE ELSE'S FRIEND OR VICE
VERSA, THESE ARE UNIVERSAL
QUESTIONS THAT DON'T DEPEND AS
MUCH ON AGE AND WHAT WE HAVE
IS THE CAPACITY OFTEN TO
REASONS THROUGH IT.
SO ILLOGICAL CONCLUSIONS CAN
COME TO KIDS AND THEY NEED TO
TEST OUT WITH THEIR PARENTS
FOT RELATED TO ANYTHING BAD
YOU YOU DID.
NO, YOU COULDN'T HAVE DONE
ANYTHING IN ORDER TO SAVE THE
PEOPLE THERE AND WE ARE
LOOKING OUT FOR YOU, BUT YOU
WANT TO BE OUT THE LOOK ROUTE
FOR, IS THERE AN I REMEMBRRATIO
IDEA IN MY KID'S HEAD.
I'LL BE IN A COLLEAGUE'S
OFFICE ASAP.
>> Uma: ABSOLUTELY, AND AS WE
SAW EARLIER A LOT OF CHILDREN
ARE GOING TO HAVE NIGHTMARES
FOR DAYS FOR THOSE THAT
SURVIVE AND THOSE WATCHING
JUST ON TELEVISION.
WHAT'S THE BEST ADVICE YOU
HAVE FOR PARENTS WHO ARE
DEALING WITH THAT?
>> I THINK WHAT YOU DO,
INITIALLY YOU EXPLAIN THAT
THESE NIGHTMARES ARE AN
OUTGROWTH OF YOUR FEAR AND
NATURAL.
AND ADD REALITY, NUMBER ONE,
YOUR SCHOOL YOU CAN SAY
THANKFULLY TO MOST CHILDREN
EVERYWHERE IS ENTIRELY SAFE.
THIS IS ONE SCHOOL OF HUNDREDS
OF THOUSANDS OF SCHOOLS.
AND THE LIKELIHOOD THAT IT
WILL HAPPEN AGAIN IS VERY LOW
BUS IN THE HISTORY OF OUR
COUNTRY, THIS HAS RARELY, IF
EVER, HAPPENED, CERTAINLY NOT
TO CHILDREN EVER.
AND ONCE KIDS CAN KIND OF
THINK OF THE NUMBERS IN THAT
WAY.
THE OTHER THING, TAKE THE EVIL
OUT OF IT.
TOO MANY COMMENTTATORS SAY
EVIL VISITED THIS TOWN.
NO, IT DIDN'T.
MENTAL ILLNESS VISITED THE
TOWN AND THESE EVENTS ARE
EXPLAINABLE.
PARTLY EXPLAINABLE, NOT TO
CHILDREN, BUT THIS PERSON GOT
ILL AND COULD HAVE GOTTEN MORE
HELP.
THIS WILL BE THE CASE.
>> Uma: APPRECIATE YOU JOINING
US.
>> IT'S A PLEASURE, THANK YOU.
>> Kelly: AND WE'LL TALK TO
RICHARD BLUMENTHAL, AS A
PARENT AND PUBLIC OFFICIAL MY
HEART AND PRAYERS ARE WITH
THESE VICTIMS AND THE ENTIRE
COMMUNITY.
YOU'LL HEAR FROM HIM NEXT.
so s
my husband and I
can't stop eating 'em!
What's...that...
on your head?
Can curlers!
Tomato Basil,
Potato with bacon...
we've got a lot of empty cans.
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
FOR THEIR ANNUAL FOOTBALL TRIP.
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE.
TRAGICALLY, THEIR DDY
GOT SACKED BY BLACKOUTS.
BUT IT'S OUR TRADITION!
THAT'S ROUGHING
THE CARD HOLDER.
BUT WITH
THE Capital One Venture Card
YOU GET DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE.
[ cheering ]
ANY FLIGHT, ANYTIME.
THE SCOREBOARD DOESN'T LIE.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET? HUT!
I HAVE ME ON MY FANTASY TEAM.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
>>  AP AND TURNING TO BREAKING
NEWS FROM WASHINGTON.
WE'VE BEEN TELLING YOU THAT
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON IS RECOVERING FROM A
CONCUSSION AFTER FAINTING.
AND SHE WILL NOT BE ABLE TO
TESTIFY ON THE HEARINGS ON
BENGHAZI.
THE HOUSE HEARING IS STILL
GOING ON AND TESTIFYING IN HER
PLACE WILL BE BILL BURNS,
DEPUTY SECRETARY OF STATE AND
MEAD THE DEPARTMENT RESOURCE
THE.
THE COUNTRY, PARTICULARLY THE
STATE OF CONNECTICUT ARE
REELING FROM THE MASSACRE IN
NEWTOWN.
AND JOINING US NOW IS THE
SENATOR FROM CONNECTICUT
RICHARD BLUMENTHAL.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US.
YOU HAVE SERVED THAT STATE FOR
SO MANY YEARS AS A FORMER
ATTORNEY GENERAL AND NOW AS
ITS SENATOR.
TELL ME ABOUT NEWTOWN AND THE
PEOPLE THERE AND OBVIOUSLY,
THE COLLECTIVE SADNESS YOU'RE
TRYING TO BRING HEALING TO AND
ANSWERS TO THE MANY QUESTIONS
THEY HAVE.
>> NEWTOWN IS A NAME PROBABLY
UNKNOWN TO MOST OF AMERICA,
BUT SHOWING AMERICA AT ITS
BEST, AND FABRIC AND STRENGTH
AND RESOLVE IN THE FACE OF
THIS TRAGEDY, IT'S REALLY
EXTRAORDINARY AND IT IS COMING
TOGETHER AS AMERICA TOSS AT
ITS BEST AND THE GRIEF IS SO
DEEP AND SO REAL, YOU KNOW,
THIS IS A TOWN, SMALL TOWN
WHERE EVERYBODY KNOWS EVERYONE
ELSE AND I THINK IT'S REALLY
DEMONSTRATING ITS STRENGTH AND
PERSERVANCE.
>> Uma: AND WHAT HAS SURPRISED
YOU THE MOST AS YOU MEET WITH
ALL THE FIRST RESPONDERS THERE
AND THE PEOPLE WHO ARE WORKING
HARD TO BRING COMFORT TO THOSE
WHO ARE SUFFERING RIGHT NOW?
>> I'VE BEEN IN LAW
ENFORCEMENT FOR A LOT OF
YEARS, ATTORNEY GENERAL FOR 20
YEARS AND DEALT WITH SOME OF
CONNECTICUT'S FINEST LAW
ENFORCEMENT PROFESSIONALS, BUT
YOU KNOW, CONFIRMING THE DEATH
OF A FIVE, SIX, SEVEN-YEAR-OLD
IS NOT PART OF THE PART OF
WHAT TAUGHT IN THE POLICE
ACADEMY AND THERE ARE TEARS IN
THE ICE OF MEN AND WOMEN SO MY
HEART IS WITH THEM THAT AS
WELL AS MY PRAYERS FOR THE
VICTIMS.
AND TREMENDOUS EMOTION IN THE
TOWN AND EVERYONE INVOLVED.
>> Kelly: SENATOR RICHARD
BLUMENTHAL.
YOU HAVE A LOT OF WORK TO DO
AND AS WELL AS THE PEOPLE
THERE HELPING LAW ENFORCEMENT
IN ANY WAY THAT YOU CAN AND
MOVING FORWARD IN TERMS OF
WHAT THE STATE WILL DO AND THE
TOWN WILL DO BEYOND THIS
TRAGEDY, BUT AGAIN, SIR, THANK
YOU FOR SHARING YOUR
PERSPECTIVE AND INSIGHT INTO
YOUR HOME AREA.
>> THANK YOU, THANK YOU.
>>.
>> Kelly: PEOPLE ACROSS THE
COUNTRY ARE MOURNING THE
TRAGIC EVENTS.
WE'VE HEARD FROM THE SENATOR
OF CONNECTICUT AND WE'LL TAKE
YOU TO SOME OF THOSE EVENTS
AND HEAR WHAT MESSAGE THEY
HAVE FOR THE VICTIMS AND THEIR
FAMILIES.
♪
often comes with a set
of equally impressive
instructions ?
Shouldn't something
that's truly advanced,
not need much explanation
at all ?
With the Nokia Lumia 822
on Verizon,
there's not much to learn
because it's
powered by Windows...
to let you do more than you ever
imagined on your smartphone.
Exclusively with Data Sense--
a feature that makes
the most of your plan.
Only on Verizon.
>>  26 CANDLES LIT UP THE
CHURCH.
HUNDREDS STANDED OUTSIDE
PRAYING AND SINGING AND TRYING
TO MAKING SENSE OF THE
INEXPLICABLE CAN BE PART OF
THE TRAGEDY LIKE THE ONE IN
CONNECTICUT.
A LOT OF PEOPLE TURN TO THEIR
FAITH TRYING TO GET THEM
THROUGH THE THE DARKEST DAYS
AND THE PASTOR JOINS US NOW TO
HELP US SHED LIGHT ON WHAT
PEOPLE GO THROUGH HAVING THEIR
FAITH CHALLENGED OR PERHAPS
WONDERING WOULD GOD ALLOW SUCH
AN EVIL DASTARDLY DEED ENACTED
AS YESTERDAY.
PAST
PASTOR, WHAT DO YOU SAY ABOUT
THAT?
>> IT HURTS THE HEART OF GOD
BECAUSE GOD HATES THIS AND I
CANNOT EVEN THINK ABOUT WHAT
PEOPLE ARE GOING THROUGH, THE
FAMILIES AND THE LOVED ONES OF
THOSE LITTLE CHILDREN AND
ADULTS TAKEN AND THE QUESTION
IS WHY AND THAT'S A TOUGH
QUESTION.
WHY DID GOD ALLOW THIS TO
HAPPEN.
WE HAVE A FREEDOM OF CHOICE
AND SO OFTEN OUR DECISIONS
HAVE GREAT CONSEQUENCES A
SOMEONE MAKES A DECISION LIKE
THE KILLER DID, THAT IS SO
HEINOUS AND SO EVIL THAT IT
AFFECTS INNOCENT PEOPLE AND WE
LIVE IN A PLACE THAT'S NOT
PERFECT AND BAD THINGS HAPPEN
TO GOOD PEOPLE AND GOD'S VERY
STRAIGHT FORWARD ABOUT THAT IN
HIS SCRIPTURES.
>> I'M GLAD YOU MENTIONED THE
SCRIPTURES, THE PRESIDENT, THE
COMMANDER-IN-CHIEF ACTED AS A
CONSOLER IN CHIEF.
PSALM 147, HE HEALS AND BINDS
UP THEIR WOUNDS.
HOW DID THAT AFFECT YOU TO
HEAR IT FROM THE PRESIDENT.
>> FOR HIM TO QUOTE SCRIPTURE,
THAT'S WHAT WE NEED TO DO, WE
NEED TO BE READY AND ABLE TO
HELP THOSE IN NEED AND WE HAVE
TO REALIZE, TOO, THAT THOSE
LITTLE ONES ARE IN HEAVEN WITH
THE LORD HIMSELF, AND WE HAVE
TO MOVE AFTER THIS GRIEVING
PERIOD FROM WHY TO WHAT, NOT
JUST WHY ME, BUT AFTER WE
GRIEVE, WHAT NOW?
THE BIBLE WILL TELL US TAKE
HELLACIOUS THINGS LIKE THIS
AND USE IT IT IT FOR THEIR
PURPOSES AND I DON'T
UNDERSTAND THAT AND I DON'T
THINK WE WILL UNTIL WE GETS TO
THE OTHER SIDE, BUT THAT'S
WHAT GOD TELLS US.
>> Kelly: AND MANY WOULD SAY
THAT THAT IS THE MYSTERY OF
GOD, THE ROMANS 12, WEEP WITH
THOSE WHO WEEP AND MOURN WITH
THOSE WHO MOURN AND THAT'S
WHAT THE READING HAS TO DO
WITH THE PRESIDENT AND OTHERS
SAY MOURN WITH THE COMMUNITY
AND PRAY WITH THE COMMUNITY.
>> THAT'S TRUE AND IT'S
INTERESTING, TOO, HOW THE
THINGS ARE GOING WELL, SO
OFTEN WE DO NOT LOOK TO GOD OR
TALK TO GOD YET, AFTER A
TRAGEDY, WE'RE THE FIRST TO
BLAME GOD.
LIKE, GOD WHERE WERE YOU?
AND GOD'S ALWAYS WHERE HE'S
BEEN, BUT IT BREAKS THE HEART
OF GOD TO SEE THIS YET, WE'RE
NOT MADE AS ROBOTS, WE HAVE A
CHOICE AND TO SAY THAT OUR
CHOICES IS JUST PRIVATE IS
TOTALLY BOGUS BECAUSE THE
CHOICES AND DECISIONS THAT WE
MAKE AFFECT NOT ONLY
OURSELVES, BUT OTHERS AND
INNOCENT BYSTANDERS.
>> Kelly: PASTOR ED YOUNG, WE
THANK YOU FOR THEIR WONDERFUL
INSIGHTS FROM THE HEART OF
GOD.
>> Uma: AND THIS INVESTIGATION
IS JUST BEGINNING AND WE'RE
LEARNING MORE AS THEY UNFOLD.
AND WE'LL RECAP WHAT WE KNOW
SO FAR.
STAY WITH US.
DOCTOR TOLD ME CM
IS EFFICIENTLY ABSORBED IN SMALL
CONTINUOUS AMOUNTS.
Citracal Slow Release
CONTINUOUSLY RELEASES CALCIUM
PLUS D
WITH EFFICIENT ABSORPTION
IN ONE DAILY DOSE.
Citracal Slow Release.
WITH EFFICIENT ABSORPTION
IN ONE DAILY DOSE.
AVOID BAD.FATS.
DON'T GO OVER 2000...
1200 CALORIES A DAY.
CARBS ARE BAD. CARBS ARE GOOD.
THE STORY KEEPS CHANGING.
SO I'M NOT LISTENING...
TO ANYONE BUT MYSELF.
I KNOW BETTER NUTRITION
WHEN I SEE IT:
GREAT GRAINS.
GREAT GRAINS CEREAL STARTS
WHOLE AND STAYS WHOLE.
SEE THE SEAM?
MORE PROCESSED FLAKES LOOK
NOTHING LIKE NATURALRAINS.
YOU CAN'T ARGUE WITH
NUTRITION YOU CAN SEE.
GREAT GRAINS.
SEARCH GREAT GRAINS
AND SEE FOR YOURSELF.
FOR MULTI GRAIN FLAKES TT ARE
ANXCELLENT SOURCE OF FIBER
TRY GREAT GRAINS
BANANA NUT CRUNCH
AND CRANBERRY ALMOND CRUNCH.
WHY LET CONSTIPATION
STRY MIRALAX.?
MIRLAX WORKSDIFFERENTLY THAN
OTHER LAXATIVES.
IT DWS WATER INTO YOUR COLON
TO UNBLOCK YOUR
SYSTEM NATURALLY.
DON'T WAIT TO FE GREAT.
MIRALAX.
>>  WELL, MANY, MANY QUESTIONS
REMAIN ABOUT THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING IN CONNECTICUT.
HERE IS A LOOK AT WHAT WE DO
KNOW.
STATE POLICE ARE NOW SAYING
THEY HAVE FOUND WHAT THEY CALL
VERY GOOD EVIDENCE THAT THEY
HOPE WILL ANSWER QUESTIONS
ABOUT THE GUNMAN'S MOTIVES.
BUT ONE LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIAL SAYS THEY HAVEN'T
FOUND A NOTE OR A MANIFESTO OF
THE SORT THAT SOMETIMES TURNS
UP AFTER SUCH ATTACKS.
IN FACT, TOWN OFFICIALS SAY
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL'S
POPULAR PRINCIPAL WAS EVEN
KILLED WHILE LUNGING FOR THE
GUNMAN AS SHE TRIED TO STOP
HIM U.
>> Uma: AUTHORITIES ARE SAYING
THAT 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA
WAS NOT VOLUNTARILY ALLOWED
INTO THAT SCHOOL.
INSTEAD, HE FORCED HIS WAY IN.
AS YOU MUST KNOW BY NOW THE
TRAGEDY IS 27.
SIX ADULTS AND 20 CHILDREN
RANGING FROM FIVE TO TEN YEARS
OLD WERE KILLED IN THE
MASSACRE AND NAMES SET TO BE
RELEASED SHORTLY AND ANOTHER
VICTIM FOUND AT THE SHOOTER'S
HOME IS A RELATIVE BELIEVED TO
BE LANZA'S MOTHER.
AND OFFICIALS ARE ON THE WAY
TO THE SEEN AND EXPECT TO HEAR
SOON.
THAT'S IT FROM WASHINGTON.
FOX NEWS WILL OF COURSE BRING
YOU UP TO THE MINUTE COVERAGE
OF THE CONNECTICUT TRAGEDY
WITH THE POLICE INVESTIGATION
AND WHAT'S BEING DONE TO OFFER
HELP TO THE PEOPLE OF THE
TIGHT NIGHT COMMUNITY AND WE
OF COURSE OFFER OUR PRAYERS TO
THE FAMILIES OF THE INCIDENT