SNOTE
>> Gretchen: GOOD MORNING,
EVERYBODY.
I AM GRETCHEN CARLSON.
THANKS FOR SHARING YOUR TIME
WITH US ON THIS VERY IMPORTANT
NUSE DAY.
THE PRESIDENT THE NATION IN
MOURNING WITH ONE CLEAR
NATION.
>> WE CAN'T TOLERATE THIS
ANYMORE.
THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
AND TO END THEM WE MUST
CHANGE.
>> Gretchen: SO WE WILL BE
LIVE FOR YOU IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT WITH MORE FROM THE
PRESIDENT.
>> Peter: THERE IS NEW
INFORMATION ON THE SHOOTER HIS
MOTHER AND WHAT THEIR
RELATIONSHIP TELLS US ABOUT A
POSSIBLE MOTIVE.
>> Brian: I LITTLE GIRL PLAYED
DEAD TO SAVE HER OWN LIFE.
HER STORE TORE STRAIGHT AHEAD.
FOX AND FRIENDS STARTS RIGHT
NOW.
>> Peter: WELCOME, FOLKS, IT
IS MONDAY MORNING AND FOX AND
FRIENDS.
THE PRESIDENT WAS AT THE
INNERFAITH SERVICE IN
CONNECTICUT.
THE GOVERNOR SAID THAT FRIDAY
WAS THE HARDEST, TOUGHEST DAY
OF HIS PRESIDENCY.
TODAY IT CONTINUES WITH TWO OF
THE LITTLE BOYS LAID TO REST.
>> Brian: IF YOU SAW THE
SPEECH, YOU COULD SEE HE WAS
HAVING A TOUGH TIME.
EVEN THOUGH HE'S DONE IT FOUR
TIMES IT IS NOT EASIER IT IS
GETTING HARDER.
HE SEES HIS KIDS IN THOSE KIDS
AS ALL OF US DO.
>> Gretchen: EVEN IF YOU ARE
NOT A PARENT YOU FEEL THE
HORRIBLENESS.
THIS IS A TRYING DAY WITH MANY
MORE TO COME.
AHEAD IN NEW TON, THE FIRST
FUNERALS WILL BE HELD FOR THE
YOUNGEST VICTIM.
NOAH POSNER TURNED 6 LAST
MONTH.
HIS TWIN SISTER ESCAPED.
JACK PINTO MAY BE BURIED IN
HIS JINT -- GIANT JERSEY.
JOINING US MORE FROM THE
PRESIDENT IS PETER DOOCY.
>> GOOD MORNING GRETCHEN.
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S TRIP CAME
AFTER THE INNOCENT STUDENTS
AND TEACHERS WERE KILLED AND
ONE DAY BEFORE THE TIGHT-KNIT
COMMUNITY MUST BURY 20 CHILD
SIZED COFFINS.
>> I AM MINDFUL THAT MERE
WORDS CAN'T MATCH THE DEPTHS
OF YOUR SORROW, NOR CAN THEY
HEAL YOUR WOUNDED HEARTS.
I CAN ONLY HOPE THAT IT HELPS
YOU TO KNOW THAT YOU ARE NOT
ALONE IN YOUR GRIEF AND THAT
OUR WORLD, TOO, HAS BEEN TORN
APART.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA MET PRIVATE
LOW IN CLASSROOMS WITH
FAMILIES OF THE 26 INNOCENT
PEOPLE WHO LOST THEIR LIVES ON
FRIDAY.
THE PRINCIPAL'S DAUGHTER
TWEETED A PHOTO.
MY MOM WOULD BE SO PROUD TO
SEE PRESIDENT OBAMA TO HOLD
HER GRAND DAUGHTER.
BUT NOT AS PROUD AS I AM OF
HER.
EMILY PARKER'S FAMILY SHOWED
SOMBER MOMENTS OF THE DEMANDER
IN CHIEF AND OTHER MILES.
WE HAVE CONFIRMED THAT ADAM
LANZA VISITED ONE GUN RANGE
AND FIRED HUNDREDS OF SHOTS .
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL USE POWER
TO MAKE SURE THIS NEVER
HAPPENS AGAIN.
>> WE SAY WE ARE TRULY DOING
ENOUGH TO GIVE ALL OF THE
CHILDREN OF THIS COUNTRY THE
CHANCE THEY DESERVE TO LIVE
OUT THEIR LIVES WITH HAPPINESS
AND PURPOSE.
I'VE BEEN REFLECTING ON THIS
THE LAST FEW DAYS AND IF WE
ARE HONEST WITH OURSELVES, THE
ANSWER IS NO.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA MADE A CALL
TO ACTION THAT WAS RECEIVED
WELL BY THE TOWNS PEOPLE.
THEY WERE EMOTIONAL IN THE
PRAYERS AND SPEECHES.
ONE MAN SAID HE HOPES
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL FOLLOW
THROUGH TO MAKE SURE SOMETHING
THAT HAPPENED HERE ON FRIDAY
NEVER HAPPENS AGAIN.
>> Peter: IT IS TIME TO TAKE
THE MASS OUT OF MASS MURDER .
>> Gretchen: SO MANY ISSUES TO
DISCUSS.
VILEN VIDEO GAMES AND MENTAL
ILLNESS AND GUN CONTROL AND I
MEAN.
>> Peter: THE TELEVISION AND
CULTURE ITSELF.
IT IS HARDENED.
>> Gretchen: WE DON'T KNOW
WHAT THE ANSWER IS IF IT IS A
CONGLOMERATION OF THEM.
THERE IS AN AMAZING STORY OF
MANY THAT IS COMING OUT OF THE
ONE PARTICULAR FIRST GRADE
CLASS WHERE EVERY 15 CHILD
EXCEPT FOR ONE LITTLE GIRL .
HOW DOES A SIX YEAR OLD LITTLE
GIRL HAVE THE UNDERSTANDING TO
PLAY DEAD AND PRETEPPED SHE
WAS SHOT AND DEAD SO THAT THE
SHOOTER WILL LEAVE HER ALONE.
THAT'S WHAT ONE SIX YEAR OLD
DID AND THEIR FAMILY IS
FEELING SURVIVOR GUILT BUT SHE
IS ALIVE.
>> Brian: SHE WALKED OUT FROM
THE BUILDING WITH BLOOD ON HER
.
SHE SAID I AM ALIVE BUT MY
FRIENDS ARE DEAD.
>> Peter: THE STORY WAS
REVEALED WHEN THE MOTHER
ATTENDED A GRIEF-COUNSELING
SESSION .
WE ARE LEARNING MORE ABOUT
ADAM LANZA AND HIS MOTHER
NANCY.
THERE IS A STORY APPARENTLY
SHE WAS A DOTING MOTHER.
THERE HE IS FROM THE TECH CLUB
YEAR BOOK PICTURE.
HE WAS 20 YEARS OLD AND SHE
WAS TRYING TO HELP HIM BUILD A
LIFE FOR HIMSELF .
THEY WERE CONSIDERING A MOVE
FOR A NEWTOWN FOR COLLEGE .
YOU HEARD HE WAS A NEAR
GENIUS.
THE THEORY WAS HE WAS LOOKING
AT ENGINEERING SCHOOLS AND
PERHAPS THEY HAD VISITED SOME
IN THE CAROLINAS AND AND SHE
WAS READY TO MOVE WITH HIM AND
HELP AIM ADAPT AND ADOPT A
NEWTOWN.
>> Brian: SHE HAD TOLD A
FRIEND IN A SPORTS BAR.
SHE WASENDLESSLY UPBEAT.
HE WAS BURNING HIMSELF WITH A
LIGHTER .
HE COULD NOT FEEL PHYSICAL
PAIN AND WAS BURNING HIMSELF
WITH A LIGHTER WITH ARMS AND
ANKLES AND SHE FEEL SHE ALWAYS
TALKED ABOUT THE OTHER ONE BUT
NOT HIM.
A FEW DAYS BEFORE THE KILLING
SHE SAID HE TOOK A PHOTOCOPY
CALL AND SHE QUICKLY CHANGED
THE SUBJECT.
>> HE WOULD GET NERVOUS AND
HIS FACE WOULD TURN BRIGHT RED
AND HE WOULD GET FIDGETY.
IT WAS DIFFICULT FOR HIM TO
SAY WHAT HE WANTED TO SAY.
HE MUST HAVE REALLY FELT
UNCOMFORTABLE IN ANY SOCIAL
SITUATION BECAUSE HE NEVER PUT
HIMSELF OUT THERE AND I JUST
DON'T REMEMBER HIM EVER
STEPPING FORWARD OR REALLY
SAYING ANYTHING.
HE WANTED TO BE LEFT ALONE AND
WE LEFT HIM ALONE.
>> Brian: NANCY WAS DEDICATED
AND DID A LOT OF VOLUNTEER
WORK AND WAS UPBEAT.
OBVIOUSLY THE WISDOM OF
TEACHING A KID WHO CAN'T FEEL
PAIN AND SHOOT A GUN AND HAVE
THEM IN HER POSSESSION AND
KNOWING SHE DIDN'T KNOW HOW TO
GET TO THIS KID, I QUESTION
THAT?
>> Gretchen: APPARENTLY SHE
WAS TRAINING BECAUSE SHE FELT
LIKE THE ECONOMY WAS GOING TO
COLLAPSE OR THE WORLD WAS
COMING TO AN END.
>> Brian: DAILY MAIL SAID
THAT.
>> Peter: SHE GOT THE GUPS
AFTER THE DIVORCE BECAUSE SHE
WAS LIVING IN THE GREAT BIG
HOUSE SHE GOT IN THE
SETTLEMENT.
YOUNG ADAM LANZA IN MIDDLE
SCHOOL WAS FLAGGED BY THE
SECURITY OFFICERS TO KEEP AN
EYE ON HIM AND WATCH OUT FOR
HIM, QUOTE, THE WORRY WAS NOT
THAT HE WAS DANGEROUS OR HE
COULD A VICTIM OR HURT HIMSELF
OR BE HURT BY OTHERS .
HE WAS ASSIGNED A PERMANENT
PSYCHICOLOGIST WHO MONITORED
HIM THROUGHOUT THE TIME HE WAS
THERE.
IN FACT, IT WAS THE COOL THAT
SUGGESTED HE JOIN THE TECH
CLUB THAT FILMED THE EVEPTS.
HE GOOD AT GISMO.
>> Brian: HE WAS HOME SCHOOLED
AND THE MOM WAS UNHAPPY AND
PULLED HIM OUT.
>> Peter: NOT ONLY SANDY HOOK
HIGH SCHOOL WHERE THE MEMORIAL
WAS LAST NIGHT, HE DID GO FOR
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
AS WELL >> Brian: WESTERN
CONNECTICUT AT 16.
>> Peter: EXACTLY.
PROBABLY MANY OF YOU WENT TO
CURCH HAD OVER THE WEEKEND.
MAYBE I WILL SHARE WITH YOU
WHAT WE DID IN OUR CHURCH ONE
OF THE MOST MOVING SERVICES I
HAVE BEEN IN, IN MY LIFE.
A MANHUNT UNDERWAY FOR THE
GUNMAN WHO SHOT AND KILLED TWO
TO PECKA OFFICERS.
22 YEAR OLD DAVID TUSKRENO
OPENED FIRE ON THE OFFICERS
OUTSIDE OF A GROCERY STORE AS
THEY RESPOPPEDED TO A CALL.
A 50 YEAR OLD WAS KILLED.
HIS SON IS A POLICE OFFICER 29
YEAR OLD JESS ATHERLY WHO JUST
JOINED THE FORCE LAST YEAR.
MOST DETAILED REPORT ON THE
BENGHAZI TERROR ATTACK COULD
BE RELEASED TODAY.
THEY WILL DELIVER THE
ASSESSMENT TO THE STATE
DEPARTMENT.
THE STATE DEPARTMENT WILL MAKE
RECOMMENDATIONS ON IMPROVING
SECURITY.
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON IS NOT TESTIFYING AS
PLANT AFTER FAINTING AND
SUFFERING A CONCUTION .
JOHN KERRY IS APPARENT LEIN
FOR THE POST.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL NOMINATE
SEPTEMBEROR JOHN KERRY AS NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE.
SUSAN RICE, THE UN AMBASSADOR
BEING CONSIDERED BUT DROPPED
OUT OF THE RUNNING AFTER BEING
CRITIZED AFTER BLAMING THE
BENGHAZI ATTACK ON A
SPONTANOUS ATTACK.
A SOLDIER TOUCHES DOWN TO SEE
HIS NEW BORN BABY GIRL ENTER
INTO THE WORLD.
SERGEANT KARICK HAD BEEN AWAY
IN STAN STAN.
>> IT WAS SPECIAL AND I CAN'T
EXPLAIN IT THE TIMING WAS
AMAZING AND JUST BEING ABLE TO
COME HOME.
>> I WAS THOUGHT DADDY HERE'S
MACY.
THEY RAN ON TO HIM AND DONE
BOTHER.
>> Gretchen: THE RED CROSS
ARRANGED THE FLIGHT.
HIS DAUGHTER NINE POUND THREE
OUNCES AND JOINING TWOS AND A
BROTHER.
IT IS A GREAT WAY TO END THE
FIRST FLOCK WHEN YOU SEE THE
FAMILY COMING BACK TOGETHER.
>> Peter: SHE SAW THE SANDY
HOOK SHOOTER AND SOMEHOW
SURVIVED.
>> YOU KNOW, IT IS A HORRIBLE
FEEL JUST LIKE A NIGHTMARE AND
I COULDN'T BELIEVE AND I THINK
IT IS A BAD DREAM.
>> Peter: HOW SHE MADE IT OUT
ALIVE.
>> Brian: THE SEARCH FOR
ANSWERS CONTINUE .
HOW DID AN HONOR ROLL STUNE
TURN INTO A MADMAN AND MASS
KILLER .
BEGIN.
TOMATO,
OBVIOUSLY.
HAHA. THERE'S MORE
THAN THAT THOUGH,
THERE'S A KICK TO IT.
WAHLALALALALLALA!
SMOOTH, BUT CRISP.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE DRINKING
A FOOD THAT'S A DRINK,
OR A DRINK THAT'S A FOOD,
WOOOOOH!
[ Male Announcer ] TASTE IT
AND DESCRIBE THE INDESCRIBABLE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
[ coughs ]
[ baby crying ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
ROBITUSSIN® LIQUID FORMULA
SOOTHES YOUR THROAT ON CONTACT
AND THE ACTIVE INGREDIENT
RELIEVES YOUR COUGH.
ROBITUSSIN®. DON'T SUFFER
THE COUGHEQUENCES™.
AND WITH MY BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CREDIT CARD,
I LOVE 'EM EVEN MORE.
I EARN 1% CASH BACK EVERYWHERE,
EVERTIME.
2% ON GROCERIES.
3% ON GAS.
AUTOMATICALLY.
NO HOOPS TO JUMP THROUGH.
THAT'S 1% BACK ON...
[ toy robot sounds ]
2% ON PUMPN PIE.
AND APPLE.
3% BACK ON 4 TRIPS
TO THE AIRPORT.
IT'S AS EASY AS..
-[ man ] 1...
-[ woman ] 2...
[ woman ] 3.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CARD.
APPLY ONLINE OR AT
A BANK OF AMERICA NEAR YOU.
>> 15 MINUTES AFTER THE TOP OF
THE HOUR.
WE ARE EXPECTING TO LEARN MORE
ABOUT THE INVESTIGATION IN
FRIDAY'S SCHOOL SHOOTING AT A
NEW'S CONFERENCE LATER THIS
MORNING.
THEY ARE LIVE FOR US IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT WITH THE
DETAILS, GOOD MORNING, ROBERT.
>> WE ARE STAND NOTHING --
STANDING IN TREADWELL PARK .
WE EXPECT ANOTHER NEW'S
CONFERENCE AT NINE O'CLOCK
EASTERN TIME AS YOU SAID .
POLICE ARE WEEKS AWAY FROM
LEARNING WHAT MADE THE GUNMAN
GO ON A RAMPAGE.
THE GUNMAN IS 20 YEAR OLD ADAM
LANZA.
HE SHOT HER IN THE HOME AND
THEN WENT TO SANDY HOOK AND
DID TRETHENDOUS AMOUNT OF
DAMAGE .
HE HAD THREE DIFFERENTS.
BUT HE DID THE BULK OF HIS
SHOOTING WITH A BUSHMASTER
ASSAULT RIFLE .
MANY MILITARIES BECAUSE THEY
INFLICT MASSIVE DAMAGE.
HE TURNED ONE OF THE TWO HAND
GUPS ON HIMSELF .
>> ALL WEAPONS HAVE MULTIPLE
MAGAZINES AND ADDITIONAL
AMMUNITION .
>> IT WAS PARKED OUTSIDE OF
THE SCHOOL .
>> AS AWFUL AS THE TRAGEDY
WAS, IT COULD HAVE BEEN WORSE.
POLICE SAY THERE WERE HUNDREDS
OF BULLETS NEAR LANZA'S BODY
AND MAGAZINES.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH, ROBERT.
WE'LL GO OVER TO THE GUYS NOW.
>> TELL US ABOUT THE CRIME AND
HOW HE WAS CARRIED OUT.
NROD, WHAT CAN YOU TELL US
ABOUT THE MOTIVE?
>> I IT TELL YOU THAT THE --
CAN TELL YOU THAT IS THE
QUESTION OF THE DAY.
THEY ARE DOING A HISTORICAL
ANALYSIS REGARDING ADAM LANZA
ASK TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHEN
HE BECAME THE TICKING TIME
BOMB.
I BELIEVE QUITE A FEW PEOPLE
IN THE COMMUNITY WAS FAMILIAR
WITH ADAM LANZA.
THE QUESTION IS WHY DID HE GO
TO THE SCHOOL?
I THINK HE KILLED HIS MOTHER
BECAUSE HE FELT LIKE I THINK
HE FELT HIS MOTHER BETRAYED
HIM.
THE MOTHER SAID SHE FELT SHE
WAS LOSING HIM.
THIS IS CONSISTENT WITH
SOMEONE WHO HAS MENTAL ISSUES.
HE WAS A MAJOR THREAT TO
OTHERS.
>> Peter: THIS IS REPORTED
TODAY.
APPARENTLY THE MOTHER AND SON
WERE CONSIDERING TO LEAVE TOWN
AND GOING TO A NEWTOWN FOR HIM
TO GO TO A ENGINEERING SCHOOL.
WHAT IF SHE WAS PUSHING HIM TO
GIT OUT ON HIS OWN.
SHOW WAS PUSHING HIM AND MAYBE
HOE DIDN'T WANT TO MOVE.
>> THATAGITATED HIM.
A PERSON THAT IS MENAL LOW
UNSTABLE DOESN'T WANT TO BE
TOLD WHAT TO DO OR WHERE TO
GO.
AND EVEN IF THE MOTHER WAS
TRYING TO GET THIS GUY THROUGH
THE COWERS TO BE PSYCHOLOGICAL
EVALUATED.
THEY WOULD HAVE TAKEN SEVERAL
OFFICERS BECAUSE HE WAS A
DANGER .
HE WAS GOING DOWN THAT PATH
QUICKLY.
I DON'T BELIEVE THEY THOUGHT
AT ANY POINT HE WOULD TAKE IT
TO THIS LEVEL.
AND THE OTHER QUESTION THAT
POLICE ARE TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT WHERE DID HE GET THE
AMMUNITION AND HOW DID HE
ACQUIRE IT?
>> NOT SOLD TO HIM.
WHO SOLD IT TO HIS MOM .
>> IF IT WAS SOLD TO HIS MOM .
WHY WOULD HIS MOTHER HAVE SO
MUCH AMMUNITION?
I WOPPEDER IF THEY SOLD IT TO
HIM?
THE GRIM REALITY HE HAD NO
CRIMINAL HISTORY AND BELIEVE
IT OR NOT, BASED ON THE
SITUATION RIGHT NOW .
HE COULD HAVE WENT OUT AND
BOUGHT HIS OWN HANDGUNS
WITHOUT BEING STOPPED.
SO THAT IS WHAT IS REALLY
SCARY.
>> Peter: MORE DETAILS AND THE
CONNECTICUT POLICE ARE
JUDICIOUS ON WHAT HAY RELEASE.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Brian: NEXT UP ON THE SHOW.
ENVELOPE ENVELOPE -- NFL SHOW
TURNS UGLY.
>> Peter: WHY WILL THE WHITE
HOUSE NOT TAKE A DEAL?
STU VARNEY ON DECK WITH THAT.
n p
and it's so rich
and creamy...
is it really 100 calories?
Let me put you on webcan...
...lean roasted chicken...
and a creamy broth
Mmm
I can still see you.
[ Male announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
[ Male Announcer ]
HOW COULD A LUMINOUS
PROTEIN IN JELLYFISH,
IMPACT LIFE EXPECTANCY
IN THE U.S.,
REAL ESTATE IN HONG KONG,
AND THE OPTICS INDUSTRY
IN GERMANY?
AT T. ROWE PRICE,
WE UNDERSTAND THE CONNECTIONS
OF A COMPLEX, GLOBAL ECONOMY.
IT'S JUST ONE REASON
OVER 75% OF OUR MUTUAL FUNDS
BEAT THEIR 10-YEAR
LIPPER AVERAGE.
T. ROWE PRICE.
INVEST WITH CONFIDENCE.
REQUEST A PROSPECTUS
OR SUMMARY PROSPECTUS
WITH INVESTMENT INFORMATION,
RISKS, FEES AND EXPENSES
TO READ AND CONSIDER CAREFULLY
BEFORE INVESTING.
>> Brian: AN AFTER MATH OF AN
OVER NIGHT BOMB IN KABUL, STAN
STAN.
A U.S. MILITARIOR - MILITARY
CONTRACTOR.
CAROLINA PANTH THERS -
PANTHERS CELEBRATES AND ALL OF
THE SUDDEN THE GUARD RAIL
COLLAPSES .
NO WORD YET ON IF ANYBODY WAS
HURT.
GRETCH.
>> Gretchen:, BRIAN.
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER
REMOVING A STUMBLING BLOCK.
RAISING TAX RATE FOR THOSE
MAKING A MILLION OR MORE?
COULD THIS SEAL A DEAL WITH
THE WHITE HOUSE.
HOLD YOUR HORSES.
THIS IS FAR FROM A DONE DEAL.
>> THIS IS A VERY IMPORTANT
SHIFT.
SPEAKER BOEHNER IS RETREATING
ON AN ISSUE PRINCIPLE AND SAID
YOU CAN RAISE TAX RATES ON
WEALTHY PEOPLE .
PREVIOUSLY HE SAID WE'LL GET
MORE MONEY OUT OF LIMITING
DEDUCTIONS.
IT IS AN IMPORTANT MOVE AND A
STEP TO A DEAL BY SPEAKER
BOEHNER.
YOU CAN HAVE HIGHER TAX RATES
ON MECHANICS - INCOMES OF A
MILLION AND MATCHED THE
PRINCIPLE OF PRESIDENT OBAMA.
TWO SIDES ARE STILL FAR APART
BUT THEY UNITED ON THE
PRINCIPLE OF HIGHER TAX RATE.
>> Gretchen: THERE WERE
REPUBLICANS SAYING YOU WILL
NOT GET AWAY WITHOUT RAISING
TAX RATES ON PEOPLE MAKING
OVER A MILLION DOLLARS .
>> YES.
>> Gretchen: I AM WONDERING IN
THE PRIVATE MEETINGS THE
SPEAKER MET WITH THE
PRESIDENT.
THE PRESIDENT MUST HAVE
ACQUEDSED.
>> WE SIMPLY DONE KNOW THAT.
I HAVE NO IDEA WHETHER HE DID
OR NOT.
THE BALL IS IN THE PRESIDENT'S
COURT.
SPEAKER BOEHNER STEPPED UP.
RAISE TAX RATOS THE VERY RICH.
>> I THINK HE WILL COME BACK
AND SAY IT IS NOT GOOD ENOUGH.
>> OF COURSE HE COULD COME
BACK LIKE THAT AND STAY HARD
ON HO HIS POSITION .
IT WILL MAKE IT THE
PRESIDENT'S FAULT IF WHY GO
OVER THE CLIFF BECAUSE HE DID
NOT RESPOND TO THE RETREAT.
A MILLION VERSUS $250,000.
IT IS NOT MUCH TIME BUT THEY
ARE A LITTLE CLOSER TOGETHER
BECAUSE THEY ARE UNITED ON
PRINCIPLE.
F WHETHER IT IS HIGHER RATES
ON $250,000 OR MILLION.
IT IS NOT GOING TO STOP OUR
DEFICIT PROBLEM.
UNLESS WE ADDRESS ENTITLEMENT
REFORM, WE'LL NOT MAKE SIG CAN
PROGRESS ON OUR MOUNTING DEBT.
>> Brian: I KNOW, IT IS A GOOD
WAY TO SUM IT UP.
YOU WILL HEAR MORE FROM STUART
VARNEY.
HAVE A GOOD ONE.
>> Peter:
>> Gretchen: SHE SAW THE
KILLER AND SURVIVED.
>> YOU KNOW, IT WAS A HORRIBLE
FEELING, AND JUST LIKE A
NIGHTMARE, THAT I COULDN'T
BELIEVE THAT, YOU THINK IT IS
A BAD DREAM.
>> Gretchen: HEAR HOW SANDY
HOOK'S SCHOOL NURSE MADE IT
OUT OF THE SCHOOL ALIVE.
>> THESE DOGS MAKING A SPECIAL
JOURNEY TO NEWTOWN IN THEIR
OWN SPECIAL WAY.
HAD ♪
[ Penélope ] I FOUND
THE BEST CAFE IN THE WORLD.
NESPRESSO.
WHERE I NEVER HAVE TO COMPROMISE
ON ANYTHING.
♪
WHERE JUST ONE TOUCH
CREATES THE PERFECT COFFEE.
WHERE EVERY CAPPUCCINO AND LATTE
IS ONLY MADE WITH FRESH MILK.
AND WHERE THE STAFF
IS EXCEPTIONALLY FRIENDLY.
♪
NESPRESSO. WHAT ELSE?
I'VE BEEN FORTUNATE TO WIN
ON GOLF'S BIGGEST STAGES.
BUT WHEN JOINT PAIN
AND STIFFNESS
FROM PSORIATIC ARTHRITIS HIT,
EVEN THE SMALLEST THINGS
BECAME DIFFICULT.
I FINALLY UNDERSTOOD WHAT
SERIOUS JOINT PAIN IS LIKE.
I TALKED TO MY RHEUMATOLOGIST
AND HE PRESCRIBED Enbrel.
Enbrel CAN HELP RELIEVE
PAIN, STIFFNESS,
AND STOP JOINT DAMAGE.
BECAUSE Enbrel, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS,
SOMETIMES FATAL EVENTS
INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS,
LYMPHOMA, OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING Enbrel,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START Enbrel IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILEN Enbrel, YOU
EXPERICE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING, OR PALENESS.
[ Phil ]
GET BACK TO THE THINGS
THAT MATTER MOST.
ASK YOUR RHEUMATOLOGIST
IF Enbrel IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
[ Doctor ]
Enbrel, THE NUMBER ONE
BIOLOG MEDICINE
PRESCRIBED BY RHEUMATOLOGISTS.
YOU WON'T JUST
FIND US ONLINE,
YOU'LL ALSO FIND US IN PERSON,
WITH DEDICATED SUPPORT TEAMS
AT OVER 500 BRANCHES
NATIONWIDE.
SO WHEN YOU CALL OR VISIT,
YOU CAN ASK FOR A NAME
YOU KNOW.
BECAUSE PERSONAL SERVICE
STARTS WITH A REAL PERSON.
[ Rodger ]
AT SCOTTRADE,
SEVEN DOLLAR TRADES
ARE JUST THE START.
OUR SUPPORT TEAMS
ARE NEARBY,
READY TO HELP.
IT'S NO WONDER SO MANY INVESTORS
ARE SAYING...
[ All ]
I'M WITH SCOTTRADE.
>> TRUCK IF YOU FEEL GOLDEN
RETRIEVERS TO HELP SHOOTING
SURVIVORS.
THE THERAPY DOGSHAVE DONE IT
BEFORE.
ANDINE THOUGH IT IS AFFECTED
BY THE TORNADOS IN JOPLIN
MISSOURI.
10 ARE IN NEWTON.
>> WE TALK ABOUT HOW DO DOGS
GO TO NURSING HOME AND
ELDARELY PEOPLE WHO CAN'T AND
TALK ABOUT PEACE AND SOMETHING
GOOD OUT OF THE STORY.
>> IF YOU WERE IN THE SCHOOL
THAT DAY, SANDY HOOK, YOU
HEARD THE WHOLE THING YOU WERE
IN THE CLASSROOMS.
THE PA SYSTEMS STAYED ON AND
SAID LOOK AT THE HORROR COMING
YOUR WAY THE NURSE KNEW
SOMETHING WAS GOING O. SHE HID
UNDER A DESK AND TALKED TO 60
MACHINES ABOUT WHAT SHE SAW
AND FEELS NOW.
>> YOU KNOW, IT WAS A
HELPLESS, HORRIBLE FEELING AND
LIKE A NIGHTMARE THAT I
COULDN'T BELIEVE THAT YOU
KNOW, YOU THINK IT IS A BAD
DREAM.
AFTER SOME TIME, IT WAS
LEN:15.
WE HAD BEEN IN THE CLOSEST FOR
AN HOUR AND A HALF, I OPENED
THE DOOR AND I PEEKED OUT AND
MY OFFICE LOOKS IN THE COURT
YARD AND I JUST SAW WHAT
LOOKED LIKE SWAT PEOPLE.
I DIDN'T KNOW WHO THEY WERE OR
SHOOTERS AND 1:15
JIGGLED THE DOOR AND I WAS
BRAVE ENOUGH TO OPEN THE DOOR
TO THE OFFICE ANDITATE POLICE
OFFICERERS WERE THERE AND THEY
WERE SURPRISED TO SEE ME.
>> SHE WAS IN THE CLOSEST WITH
A SECRETARY BARB.
WHEN THE COING - COMMOTION .
AND SHE LOOKED THROUGH THERE
AND SHE COULD ACTUALLY SEE
ABOUT FROM THE LEGS DOWN OF
THE GUNMAN AND HE CAME BY HER
DESK AND WALKED AWAY.
AND BARB DIALED 911 AND THEY
GO INTO A CLOSEST WITH TWO
HEAVY DOORS.
WHEN THEY SAW THE SWAT GUYS,
THEY DIDN'T IF THEY WERE GOOD
OR BAD.
ANOTHER STORY OF A TEACHER WHO
WAS IN A CLOSEST WITH KIDS.
SHE DIDN'T BELIEVE IT SHE MADE
THEM PUT A BADGE UNDER THE
DOORWOULD YOU BELIEVE THAT
WHEN YOU HAVE 20 KIDS IN THE
CLOSEST.
STORIES OF PANIC AND TRYING TO
KEEP YOURSELF AND CHILDREN
SAFE.
>> Peter: AND THAT PARTICULAR
STORY.
IF YOU ARE REALLY THE POLICE
YOU WILL HAVE THE KEY AND THE
GUY WENT THROUGH THE ENTIRE
LOOP OF KEYS AND OPENED THE
DOOR.
>> Brian: ONE THING ABOUT THE
SCHOOLS, THEY SAY IT WAS NOT
READY.
THIS SCHOOL PROBABLY NEVER
THOUGHT IT WOULD HAPPEN BUT
THEY WERE READY AS IT SEEMS
FOR ME AS THEY COULD BE.
LISTEN TO THE NURSE TALK ABOUT
WHAT THEY DID.
>> WE HAVE DIFFERENT KINDS OF
DRILLS IN ADDITION TO FIRE
DRILLS AND HIGH WIND AND LOCK
DOWN AND EVACUATION DRILLS.
AND SO WE'VE DONE IT.
AND BEEN DOING IT EACH MONTH
IT IS DIFFERENT.
>> YOU HAVE DONE THEM
RECENTLY?
>> YEAH.
>> Gretchen: THE PRINCIPAL WHO
WAS KILLED IN THE HORRIBLE
EVENT SHE HAD ENACTED A LOT OF
THE DRILLS FOR WHATEVER REASON
THIS YEAR.
SHE HAD INCREASED SECURITY AT
THIS SCHOOL.
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT YOU GUYS,
BRIAN AND STEVE, MY KID'S
SCHOOLS HAVE BEEN SENDING A
LOT OF E-MAILS.
WE ALSO LIVE IN CONNECTICUT
ABOUT WHAT IS THE NEW PLAN OF
ACTION NOW.
HOW DO WE MOVE FORWARD?
WE'LL HAVE ARMED SECURITY
GUARDS OUTSIDE OF THE SCHOOL
FOR TWO WEEKS.
HOW LONG DOES THAT LAST.
DO WE HAVE THE FUNDING OR DOES
IT MAKE SENSE CULTURALLY TO DO
THAT MOVING FORWARD.
THERE IS IT A LOT OF CALLS
FROM FORMER EDUCATION BILL
BENNETT.
TEACHERS SHOULD BE ARMED IN
THE SCHOOLS.
WHAT IS THE ANSWER HERE.
WHAT HAVE WE COME TO?
I AM NOT SURE ANY OF US WILL
>> Peter: THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES SAID THIPPINGS
HAVE GOT TO CHANGE.
WE ARE NOT DOING ENOUGH TO
PROTECT OUR CHILDREN.
IF ANYTHING GOOD COMES OUT OF
WHAT HAPPENED IN SANDY HOOK,
IT WILL NOT JUST BE A DIALOGUE
ABOUT GUN CONTROL.
THERE IS A LOT OF GUN LAWS ON
THE BOOKS AND THEY ARE UNEVEN.
>> Brian: AND NOT ENFORCED.
MR. #1: AND NOT JUST THE GUNS,
BUT A LARGER DISCUSSION OF HOW
TO STOP GLORIFYING VIOLENCE IN
VIDEO GAMES AND TELEVISION
SHOWS AND MOVIES AS WELL.
I GOT A FEELING WE ARE AT A
TIPPING POINT.
>> Brian: THEY HAD EVERY
OPPORTUNITY TO SAY GUNS ARE
THE PROBLEM.
AND HE'S NOT.
AND THE WAY IN WHICH HE'S
APPROACHING THIS IS
PHENOMENAL.
WE GO AND KEEP POLITICS OUT OF
IT AND COME UP WITH THE BEST
SOLUTIONS POSSIBLE.
YOU HARDEN THE TARGET.
>> Gretchen: STEVE BRINGS UP
THE TIPPING POINT.
HOW DO YOU REVERSE THAT WITH
OUR KIDS NOW?
THEY ARE SO ENTRENCHED IN THE
CULTURE OF VIDEO GAMES AND
SMACKING DOWN THIS AND THAT.
AS PARENTS, YOU INSTEAD THE
VALUES OF LOAF FOR YOUR KIDS
TO BE GOOD PEOPLE.
AND YOU ARE EXPOSED TO THAT
24-7.
HOW DO YOU ROLL IT BACK.
>> Brian: EVERYBODY WANTED TO
BE A COWBOY.
>> Peter: NOW VIDEO GAMES ARE
SO GRAPHIC AND REALISTIC.
ONE OF THE MOST POPULAR SHOWS
ON TELEVISION IS NCIS.
AND YOU GO AN HOUR WITHOUT
SOMEONE GETTING SHOT IN THE
FACE OR BLOWN UP OR
DISMEMBERED AND DISBOWELED
WITHIN AN HOUR.
>> Gretchen: MY KIDS ARE 7-9
AND I DECIDED TO SAY SOMETHING
TO THEM ABOUT IT AND IT IS
INTERESTING TO SEE CHILDREN
AND REACTION .
THEY WERE SAD, BUT I DON'T
KNOW IF THEY GET IT AT THAT
AGE, YOU DON'T WANT TO GIVE
THEM TOO MANY DETAILS.
>> Brian: THEY ARE IN A STAGE
OF MAGICAL FEELING.
YOU ARE AT A LOSS OF HOW MUCH
YOU SAY .
IT IS VERY, VERY IT IS TOUGH
TO KNOW WHAT TO SAY TO YOUR
KIDS .
>> Peter: WHEN MY KIDS WERE.
I NEVER TOLD THEM THERE WAS NO
SUCH AS MONSTERS.
I AM NOT SO SURE ANYMORE .
>> Gretchen: WITHIN DAY AFTER
A SHOOTING 47 GUNS INSIDE OF
VAUGHN MYERS HOME RIGHT NEXT
DOOR TO AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL .
MYER THREATENED TO SET HIS
WIFE ON FIRE AND SAID HE WOULD
GO TO THE SCHOOL AND KILL AS
MANY PEOPLE AS POSSIBLE.
>> Brian: TWO STATIONS IN
BENGHAZI, LIBYA WERE TARGETED
AN EXPLOSIVE DEVICE WAS THROWN
AT A PARKED CAR AND A BLAST AT
ANOTHER POLICE STATION .
NO ONE WAS HURT IN EITHER
ATTACK.
>> Peter: THE LATEST MOON
MISSIONS IS COMING TO A CRASH
UPON ENDING.
EBEB AND FLOW WILL BE
PROGRAMMED TO CRASH IN THE
MOON.
THEY HAVE BEEN ORBITING FOR A
YEAR AND CREATING A DETAIL
WOULD MAP OF THE GRAVITY
FIELD.
>> Gretchen: KATE MIDDLETON IS
BACK IN THE SPOT LIGHT AFTER A
TOUGH TWO WEEKS .
SHE WENT TO THE AWARDS SHOW
ANDED TWO AWARDS EARLIER THIS
MONTH HOSPITALIZED FOR SEVERE
MORNING SICKNESS.
SHE WAS NOT FEELING WELL FOR
THE FOUR HOUR EVENT.
IS THAT VIDEO OF HER PREGNANT
NOW .
>> Peter: I DON'T THINK THAT
IS.
THAT IS A SPORTS EVENT.
>> Brian: TOUCHING TRIBUTE TO
THE VICTIMS OF THE TRAGEDY.
THE FLARES SENT TO THE SKY.
THEY ARE PLEDGING 25,000 TO
HELP THE FAMILIES.
49ERS STAGING A MASSIVE COME
BACK.
IN THE END.
COLLIN, YOUNG GUY SIX MINUTES
LEFT PATRIOTS TRIED AN ON SIDE
KICK.
NO LUCK.
IT IS ANYONE GUESS.
RG3.
RUNNING 329 AND WATCHED HIM TO
BEAT THE BROWNS.
THEY ARE THE BEST.
NALCEDALLAS IN OVER TIME
AGAINST THE STEELERS.
BEN ROTHLESBURGER RUNS IT DOWN
TO THE ONE.
AND DAN BAILEY MADE IT.
AND GIANTS PLAY NO ONE TAPED
THE GAME AND WE HAVE NO HIGH
LIGHTS.
ATLANTA WON RUNNING BACK
ADRIAN PETERSON.
SHY OF FIVE.
AND HE BEAT THE RAMS ALONG
WITH THE MINNESOTA VIKES,
36-THAT'S THE QUICK LOOK AT
WORLD OF SPORTS.
THAT'S ONE OF FEW I SMILED.
>> Brian: I THINK HE HAD A
GREAT GAME AND HEALED FROM THE
KNEE INJURY.
>> Gretchen: HOW CAN WE STOP
ROGUE AFGHAN SOLDIERS FROM
TURNING THEIR GUNS ON OUR
TROOPS.
THEY SAID AMERICANS SHOULD BE
NICER AND RESPECT THEIR
RELIGION.
WILL THAT WORK?
>> Peter: POLICE SAY THERE IS
REASON TO BELIEVE THAT NEW TON
KILLER LOVE VIOLENT VIDEO
GAMES.
OUR GAMES TRAINING OUR KIDS TO
KILL .
STRAIGHT AHEAD .
[ fishing rod casting line,
marching band playing ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THE RHYTHM OF LIFE.
[ whistle blowing ]
WHERE DO YOU HEAR THAT BEAT?
CAMPBELL'S HEALTHY REQUEST SOUP
LETS YOU HEAR IT...
IN YOUR HEART.
[ basketball bouncing ]
HEART HEALTHY.
GREAT TASTE.
MMM...
[ Male Announcer ] SOUNDS GOOD.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
THIS IS ANOTHER!
TA-DAA!
TRY CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG.
IT CLEANS SO WELL AND YOU CAN
USE UP TO FOUR TIMES LESS
THAN THE LEADING VALUE
BRAND.
OH! THERE IT IS.
THANKS SON.
HEY!
[ Female Announcer ]
CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG
HAS A DURACLEAN TEXTURE
THAT CAN HELP YOU GET CLEAN
WHILE STILL USING LESS.
AND IT'S FOUR TIMES STRONGER
VERSUS THE LEADING VALUE BRAND.
CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG HELPS KEEP
YOU AND YOUR UNDERWEAR CLEAN.
WE ALL GO. WHY NOT ENJOY THE GO
WITH CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG?
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAN
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
>> >> Peter: GREAT HEAD LINES.
FOUNDER OF DOMINO PIZZA SUING
THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT OVER
THE LAWS MANDATORY
CONTRADECEPTION MANHE SAID
THAT LAW VIOLATES HIS RIGHTS.
AND THE WINNER OF THE TIMES
PERSON POLL OF THE YEAR.
JONG?
AND THAT IS BECAUSE THE
INTERNET FORUM FOR CHEN.
THEY MANIPULATED THE POLL.
THE MAGAZINE WILL UNVEIL THE
OFFICIAL PERSON FOR CHOICE OF
THE YEAR ON FRIDAY.
>> Brian: HE'S ALSO SEXIEST
MAN OF THE YEAR.
AFGHAN FIGHTERS X. MANY ARE
SHOOTING THE SOLDIERS IN THE
GREEN AND BLUE.
THEY ARING OUR GEWS TO BE
NICER.
CEO OF CONCERNED VET RANS FOR
AMERICA.
IT IS IT ALL ABOUT THE MANUAL
AND HOW WE OPERATE.
IS IT HURTING YOU GUYS IN THE
FIELD?
>> FIRST OF ALL, THERE ARE NO
EASY ANSWERS.
WE EXPAND HAPPENED THE STAFF
GAN ARMY RAPIDLY AND VETTING
IS DIFFICULT .
WE TALKED ABOUT IT
OFFENSIVELY.
WE HAVE AN OPTIC THAT WE ARE
NOT GOING TO BE AND THERE IS A
CULTURAL CASYM BETWEEN THE
STAN TAN AND THE UNITED
STATES.
THIS MANUAL HAS A BLAME US
FIRST MENITALITY THAT MAKES IT
MORE DIFFICULT TO BE
SUCCESSFUL GUYS ARE WALKOG EGG
SHELLS.
THEY HAVE TO RELATIONSHIP
BUILD AND IF YOU ARE
PARTNERING WITH MACHINE YOU
HAVE TO GET TO KNOWN THEM IN
YOU HUMAN WAYS .
NEVER TALK ABOUT WOMEN OR
ISLAM OR.
ALL OF THE RIDICULOUS THING IN
THE MANUAL.
IF YOU GIVE SPECIFIC AM ITEMS
NOT IT TALK ABOUT IT MAKE ITS
ACWARD.
>> Brian: GENERAL ALLEN IS NOT
PLEASED.
ISLAM.
OR SPIRITUALITY AND MAKE
DEROGATORY COMMENTS ABOUT
WOMEN'S RIGHTS AS YOU
MENTIONED.
THESE ARE SUPPOSED TO MAKE IT
BETTER.
IF THEY TALKED TO THE CAPTAINS
LIKE YOU.
THAT BETTER THAN WORKING ON IN
TAMPA?
>> SUPPOSEDLY IT IS IT BASED
ON 600 INTERVIEWS WITH AFGHANS
AND 200 MERCHES.
HOPEFULLY IT IS JUNIOR
OFFICERS.
IT IS GREAT TO SEE THE GENERAL
COME OUT STRONGLY AND SAY THIS
IS NOT HELPFUL.
YOU AND I HAVE NOT SEEN THAT.
USUALLY THE COMMANDER IS
DEFENDING IT AND SAYING IT IS
HELPFUL IN PREVENTING OUR GUYS
FROM BEING ATTACKED.
THE GENERAL ALLEN RECOGNIZES
IT IS NOT USEFUL IN CREATING
RELATIONSHIPS.
>> PEAT, I UNDERSTAND THERE
WILL BE A COMPLETE EVALUATION
OF WHERE WE ARE IN STAN STAN
AND SUPPOSED TO MAKE THINGINGS
LOOK PRETTY BLEAK.
WOULD YOU SUPPORT PULLING OUT
SOONER OR LATER?
>> I WOULDN'T, I WOULD GIVE
AND DEFER THAT TO THE
COMMANDER ON THE GROUND.
I HAVE BEEN AWAY FROM STAN
STAN IN A YEAR .
THINGS CHANGE RAPPEDLY.
IT DOESN'T SURPRISE ME THE
REPORT SHOWING A DETERIORATING
DEAD LINE.
THAT IS WHAT HAPPENS WHEN YOU
WITH DRAW.
WE'LL HAVE MORE SEGMENTS
BECAUSE IT IS MORE AND MORE
DIFFICULT AND CONTENTOUS AND
THE TREAD LINES ARE NOT GOING
IN THE RIGHT DIRECTION.
I HOPE POLICY MAKERS DON'T SAY
LET IT IMPLODE AND WE ARE
SENDING MY SON THERE 15 YEARS
FROM NOW.
>> Brian: I WANT TO GET YOUR
PERSPECTIVE.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Brian: ONE THIPPING WE
KNOW.
THAT THE NEWTOWN KILLER WAS A
FAN OF VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES
THAT PLAY A ROLE .
AND THEN THERE IS THE GUN
DEBATE.
WOULD IT MAKE A DIFFERENCE?
WE ARE LIVE IN WASHINGTON AT
THE TOP OF THE HOUR .
[ Male Announcer ]
COUGHEQUENCE™ #8.
WAKING THE BABY.
[ coughs ]
[ baby crying ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
ROBITUSSIN® LIQUID FORMULA
SOOTHES YOUR THROAT ON CONTACT
AND THE ACTIVE INGREDIENT
RELIEVES YOUR COUGH.
ROBITUSSIN®. DON'T SUFFER
THE COUGHEQUENCES™.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OURENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
>> Peter: HE LIVED IN A HOUSE
FILLED WITH GUNS AND VIOLENT
VIDEO GAMES THAT COULD HAVE
LED ADAM LANZA TO PLAY .
ARE TODAY'S TRAINING OUR
CHILDREN TO KILL?
WE HAVE A PROFESSOR FROM WEST
POINT AND AUTHOR OF THE BOOK
KILLOLOGY .
GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
>> Brian: GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
THE BOOK IS ON KILLING.
ON KILLING THE WEB SITE IS GET
BULLET PROOF MIND.COM.
AND I PREDICTED THIS GUY.
THE KIDS WHO GAVE US
JONESBORROW AND COLUMBINE AND
VIRGINIA TECH.
THIS GENERATION GIVE US A
MOVIE MASSACRE IN AURORA AND
MASSACRE IN FIRST GRADE
CLASSROOM IN SANDY HOOK.
WHEN ARE WHY GOING TO CONNECT
THE WORLD?
THE CHILDREN PLAY THE SICKEST
GAMES AND MOVIES AND COMMIT
THE SICKEST ACTS IN HISTORY .
WE HAVE TO GET TIRED OF THIS
LIVING IN THIS WORLD .
>> Peter: COLORADO WHY ARE
LOOKING AT ONE OF THE
REALISTIC VIDEO GAMES.
PEOPLE WILL SAY, HEY, IT IS
JUST A VIDEO GAME.
BUT UNLY IT DESENSE TIESES TO
AND YOU ARE JUST PULLING A ARE
TRIGGLE AND IT IS JUST A GAME.
A LOT OF THE GAMERS WENT ON TO
DO VILEN STUFF .
>> EVERYONE OF OUR SCHOOL
KILLERS.
THERE IS IT NEVER A JUVENILE
MASS MURDERER AND NOW WE HAVE
THEM.
GERMANY TWO MASSACRES IN BEAT
BOIN BINE AND FINLAND HAD
THREE ONE IN CANADA AND
BELGIUM AND SICK MAN WHO TOOK
A BUECHLER KNIFE AND HACKED
BABIES IN THE CRIBS CHINA.
THESE CRIMES NEVER HAPPENED IN
HUMAN HISTORY.
WE FEET THE SICKNESS VIDEO
GAMES.
AND I TRAIN LAW ENFORCEMENT
AND I SPEND MORE TIME ON THE
ROAD TRAINING MILITARY AND LAW
ENFORCEMENT THAN ANYBODY ELSE
IN AMERICA.
WE KNOW HOW TO USE SIMULATORS
TO CREATE CONTINUES TO ENABLE
PEOPLE TO KILL IN COMBAT.
THE CLASS AND SOCIAL LEARNING
MODELS AND DESENSITIZING AND
PROGRAMMING THAT WE PUT IN
PROGRAMS FOR COPS AND MILITARY
ARE DONE WITH THE KIDS.
WE GOT TO GET MAD AND
PASSIONATE ABOUT THE SCHOOLS
THAT REFUSE TO PROTECT OUR
KIDS.
>> Peter: YOU MADE A GREAT
POINT.
YOU SAY, IT IS OBVIOUS.
HOW DO WE FIX IT?
>> NUMBER ONE PARENTS HAVE TO
BE INFORMED.
WE HAVE LAWS AGAINST
PORNOGRAPHY AND ALCOHOL AND
SEX AND FIRE ARMS.
AND THERE ARE LAWS TO HELP THE
PARENTSMENT THE PARTNERSHIPS
HAVE TO BE REFORM WOULD.
M RATE VIDEO GAME IS SAME AS
X-.
NO CHILD UNDER 17 SHOULD PLAY
IT TIME OUT AND YOU ARE
RAISING A KILLER.
NOT EVERY KID WILL BE BUT YOU
MAY BE THE VICTIM AND IT IS ON
YOUR HANDS.
>> WE DON'T KNOW THE
CONNECTION WITH THIS KID AND
VIDEO GAMES.
>> ABSOLUTE ABSOLUTE COLONEL.
AUTHOR OF THE BOOK ON KILLING,
SIR.
THANK YOU VERY EMPLOY. >> GO
TO BULLETPROOF.COM.
TAKE A LOOK AT IT >> Peter:
STRITE AHEAD.
HE WAS THE PRINCIPAL OF
COLUMBINE FRAIN YEARS AGO AND
WHAT HE SAID NEEDS TO BE DONE
TO STOP SCHOOL VIOLENCE .
♪ IF LOVING YOU IS WRONG
♪ I DON'T WANNA BE RIGHT
[ record scratch ]
WHAT?! IT'S NOT BAD FOR YOU.
IT JUST TASTES THAT WAY.
[ Female Announcer ]
Honey Nut Cheerios CEREAL --
HEART-HEALTHY,
WHOLE GRAIN OATS.
YOU CAN'T GO WRONG LOVING IT.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>> Gretchen: GOOD MORNING,
EVERYBODY.
TODAY IS MONDAY, DECEMBER 17,
2012.
I'M GRETCHEN CARLSON THE THANKS
FOR SHARING YOUR TIME WITH US ON
THIS VERY DIFFICULT DAY.
THE COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, PREPARES FOR THE
FIRST CHILDREN'S FUNERALS ON THE
HEELS OF A VERY CLEAR MESSAGE
FROM PRESIDENT OBAMA LAST NIGHT.
>> WE CAN'T TOLERATE THIS
ANYMORE.
THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
TO END THEM, WE MUST CHANGE.
>> Gretchen: NOW THE GUN
LEGISLATION BEING CRAFTED.
WE'RE LIVE IN NEWTOWN WITH MORE
FROM THE PRESIDENT.
>> Brian: THERE IS ALSO
BRAND-NEW INFORMATION ON THE
SHOOTER AND HIS MOTHER.
WHAT THEIR RELATIONSHIP COULD
TELL BUS A POSSIBLE MOTIVE.
>> Steve: AND IT'S A STORY WE
BROKE RIGHT HERE ON "FOX &
FRIENDS."
FORMER MARINE BEING HELD IN
MEXICO ON TRUMPED UP GUN
CHARGES.
HIS MOM WILL BE HERE WITH NEW
DETAILS.
"FOX & FRIENDS" FOR THIS MONDAY
STARTS RIGHT NOW.
>> Steve: WELCOME ABOARD.
LIVE FROM STUDIO E, IF YOU WERE
WATCHING THE SERVICES LAST NIGHT
LIVE FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
YOU NOTICED THAT A NUMBER OF THE
PEOPLE INSIDE THE HALL WERE
WEARING LITTLE GREEN AND WHITE
BUTTONS.
A LITTLE RIBBON.
AND A LOT OF PEOPLE TODAY ARE
GOING TO WEAR GREEN AND WHITE TO
REMEMBER THE CHILDREN WHO WERE
MURDERED LAST FRIDAY.
>> Gretchen: SO GREEN IS THE
COLOR OF THE DAY.
LET'S MOVE FORWARD NOW WITH THIS
EMOTIONALLY TRYING DAY AHEAD IN
NEWTOWN, CON CONTINENTAL THE
FIRST FUNERALS ARE BEING HELD.
ONE FOR THE YOUNGEST VICTIM.
THIS IS NOAH POSNER.
TURNED SIX LAST MONTH HIS SISTER
MANAGED TO ESCAPE UNHARMED.
THE OTHER FUNERAL FOR
SIX-YEAR-OLD JACK PINTO.
>> Steve: HE IS A HUGE GIANTS
FANS  THAT HIS PARENTS MAY BURY
HIM IN HIS FAVORITE JERSEY.
YESTERDAY PRESIDENT OBAMA
ADDRESSED THE NATION SAYING OUR
COUNTRY CANNOT TOLERATE THIS
ANYMORE.
JOINING US WITH MORE FROM
NEWTOWN IS PETER DOOCY.
>> GOOD MORNING.
AT THIS TIME JUST THREE DAYS
AGO, SIX EDUCATORS AND 20 FIRST
GRADERS WERE GETTING READY FOR
SCHOOL LIKE ALWAYS.
BY LAST NIGHT, THE PRESIDENT OF
THE UNITED STATES WAS HERE AT A
VERY PAINFUL MEMORIAL SERVICE
READING THEIR NAMES ONE AT A
TIME.
>> I AM VERY MINDFUL THAT MERE
WORDS CANNOT MATCH THE DEPTHS OF
YOUR SORROW, NOR CAN THEY HEAL
YOUR WOUNDED HEARTS.
I CAN ONLY HOPE IT HELPS FOR YOU
TO KNOW THAT YOU'RE NOT ALONE IN
YOUR GRIEF.
OUR WORLD, TOO, HAS BEEN TORN
APART.
>> BEFORE HIS NATIONAL ADDRESS,
PRESIDENT OBAMA MET PRIVATELY
WITH FAMILIES OF THE INNOCENT
CHILDREN AND ADULTS WHO LOST
THEIR LIVES ON FRIDAY.
PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG'S
DAUGHTER TWEET ADD PHOTO WITH A
CAPTION THAT SAID, MY MOM WOULD
BE SO PROUD TO SEE PRESIDENT
OBAMA HOLDING HER GRANDDAUGHTER
BUT NOT AS PROUD AS I AM OF HER.
THE HEART BROKEN FAMILY OF EMILY
PARKER POSTED PHOTOS.
OTHERS SHOWING SMILES.
AFTER THE PRIVATE MEETING,
PRESIDENT OBAMA TOOK THE STAGE
TO PROMISE ACTION.
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS, I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT, TO MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS TO PARENTS
AND EDUCATORS IN AN EFFORT AIMED
AT PREVENTING MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS.
>> AS FOR THE STATUS OF THE
INVESTIGATION, WE NOW KNOW THAT
ADAM LANZA FIRED HUNDREDS OF
SHOTS, HUNDREDS INSIDE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENT TEAR SCHOOL SCHOOL
ON FRIDAY AND HE VISITED AT
LEAST ONE GUN RANGE WITH HIS
MOTHER ACTION ALTHOUGH AT THIS
TIME THEY CAN NOT SAY WHETHER OR
NOT HE ACTUALLY FIRED ANY
WEAPONS WHILE HE WAS AT THAT
RANGE.
BACK TO YOU IN NEW YORK.
>> Steve: THANK YOU.
>> Brian: WE KNOW THIS GUY IS
THE UTTER DEFINITION OF A LONER.
WE KNOW HE WAS EMOTIONALLY
DISABLED.
>> Steve: ALTHOUGH A NEAR
GENIUS.
>> Brian: HE HAD A MEDICAL
CONDITION AND COULD NOT FEEL
PAIN.
THEY SAY THAT HE LOVED VIDEO
GAMES.
ONE GAME IN PARTICULAR, I DON'T
KNOW ANY OF THEM, BUT CALLED
DYNASTY WARRIORS.
HIS MOM TOOK HIM SHOOTING MORE
THAN ONCE.
BUT OTHER REPORTS WERE SHE TOOK
HIM OFTEN.
THE NEIGHBORS SAY HE WAS HOME
SCHOOLED AND THAT SHE, IN FACT,
DEVOTED HER LIFE TO HIM, BUT
THAT ONE CONVERSATION AT A
SPORTS BAR THAT SHE HAD WITH
SOMEBODY A FEW DAYS AGO SAYING I
FEEL LIKE I'M LOSING HIM AND I
FEEL LIKE HE'S SLIPPING AWAY.
THAT WAS AN INDICATION THAT THEY
WERE AT A TIPPING POINT.
>> Gretchen: APPARENTLY WHEN SHE
WOULD HAVE BABY-SITTERS TAKE
CARE OF HIM, SHE WOULD SAY TO
THEM, YOU CAN NOT EVEN LEAVE HIM
ALONE EVEN TO GO TO THE
RESTROOM.
SO SHE WAS DEVOTED TO THIS
CHILD.
THERE ARE GOING TO BE A LOT OF
QUESTIONS, THOUGH, ABOUT SO MANY
THINGS WITH THIS INCIDENT.
BUT ALSO JUST ABOUT THE WAY IN
WHICH HE WAS ALLOWED TO PLAY
THESE VIDEO GAMES AND LEARN HOW
TO SHOOT GUNS AND THE ACCESS TO
THE GUNS.
ONE OF HIS CLASSMATES SPOKES TO
"60 MINUTES LAST NIGHT.
>> HE JUST WOULD GET VERY
NERVOUS AND HIS FACE WOULD TURN
BRIGHT RED AND HE WOULD GET VERY
FIDGETY.
YOU COULD JUST TELL THAT HE
WASN'T THAT HE DIDN'T KNOW THE
ANSWER.
IT WAS VERY DIFFICULT FOR HIM TO
SAY WHAT HE WANTED TO SAY.
HE MUST HAVE REALLY FELT
UNCOMFORTABLE IN ANY KIND OF
SOCIAL SITUATION BECAUSE HE
UNFORTUNATE REALLY PUT HIMSELF
OUT THERE AND I JUST DON'T
REALLY REMEMBER HIM EVER
STEPPING FORWARD OR REALLY
SAYING ANYTHING.
IT WAS JUST HE WANTED TO BE LEFT
ALONE AND WE LEFT HIM ALONE.
>> Steve: APPARENTLY AS EARLY AS
MIDDLE SCHOOL, HE WAS IDENTIFIED
BY SECURITY OFFICERS AT HIS
SCHOOL AS SOMEBODY TO WATCH AND
THEN WHEN HE WENT TO HIGH
SCHOOL, HE HAD A PERMANENT
PSYCHOLOGIST ASSIGNED TO HIM TO
KEEP AN EYE ON HIM.
THEY WERE WORRIED THAT NOT THAT
HE WOULD BE VIOLENT U ABOUT BE A
VICTIM.
ALSO APPARENTLY IN THE WEEKS
LEADING UP TO THE RAMPAGE, HE
AND HIS MOTHER HAD BEEN TALKING
A LOT ABOUT THE NEXT STAGE IN
HIS LIFE.
HE WAS 20 YEARS OLD.
SHE WAS TRYING TO HELP HIM
ESTABLISH A LIFE AND MAYBE MOVE
TO A NEW TOWN, MAYBE GO TO A
COLLEGE TO STUDY ENGINEERING
BECAUSE HE WAS BRIGHT.
AND SHE WAS READY TO GO WITH HIM
TO MOVE WITH HIM, SO THEY
VISITED SOME COLLEGES AND LOOKED
INTO VARIOUS LIVING SITUATION.
THE BIG QUESTION IS, WHAT IF HE
DIDN'T WANT TO GO.
WHAT IF IT WAS SIMPLY THE MOTHER
PUSHING HIM TO MOVE ON WITH HIS
LIFE AND HE DIDN'T WANT TO GO?
>> Gretchen: WHAT ABOUT MENTAL
ILLNESS IN OUR SOCIETY,  WHICH
IS A WHOLE NOTHER ISSUE ABOUT
IT'S VERY, VERY, VERY DIFFICULT
TO GET PEOPLE HELP BASED ON
MENTAL ILLNESS AND I'M SURE MANY
OF YOU OUT THERE HAVE
EXPERIENCED THIS, MAYBE IN YOUR
OWN FAMILY OR NOT.
THAT'S ALSO GOING TO BECOME A
CENTRAL.
>> Brian: IT COULD HAVE BEEN
WORSE.
HE HAD MORE AMMO AND IF THE
NURSE RESPONDERS DIDN'T GET
THERE, EVIDENTLY THE REPORTS ARE
THAT AS SOON AS HE SAW THE COPS
ENTER, THAT'S WHEN HE BLEW HIS
HEAD OFF.
IF HE DIDN'T, THERE WAS MORE
PEOPLE WOULD HAVE BEEN KILLED.
>> Steve: ABSOLUTELY.
AND THERE ARE STORIES THIS
MORNING THAT APPARENTLY HIS
MOTHER, NANCY, TOOK HIM TO THE
FIRE RANGES TO BOND WITH HIM.
HE WAS SOCIALLY AWKWARD AND SHE
FELT THAT'S A WAY TO DO IT.
SHE NEVER MENTIONED TO FRIENDS
THAT'S VIOLENT AND SHE WAS NEVER
AFRAID OF HIM AND YET, ON FRIDAY
MORNING, HE WOKE UP, WENT INTO
HER BEDROOM WHILE SHE WAS STILL
IN THE BED, AND SHOT HER IN THE
HEAD FOUR TIMES.
>> Gretchen: NOW LAWMAKERS
CRAFTING NEW GUN LEGISLATION.
DOUG IS LIVE WITH MORE ON THAT.
GOOD MORNING.
>> YEAH.
THIS OLD DEBATE HAS BEEN GIVEN
NEW LIFE HERE IN WASHINGTON
WHERE WE'RE LIKELY TO SEE SOME
PIECES OF LEGISLATION ADVANCE
DEALING WITH GUN CONTROL,
PERHAPS IN THE NEXT CONGRESS.
AS THE PRESIDENT SPOKE AT THAT
MEMORIAL ADDRESS LAST NIGHT IN
CONNECTICUT, HE DIDN'T
SPECIFICALLY MENTION GUN
CONTROL, BUT HE DID SAY THAT THE
NATION SHOULD DO MORE TO PROTECT
THE NATION'S CHILDREN AND IN THE
WAKE OF THE ATTACK, HE IS GOING
TO FACE PLENTY MUCH PRESSURE
FROM HIS SUPPORTERS TO CRACK
DOWN ON GUNS.
>> IT'S TIME FOR THE PRESIDENT,
I THINK, TO STAND UP AND LEAD
AND TELL THIS COUNTRY WHAT WE
SHOULD DO.
NOT GO TO CONGRESS AND SAY WHAT
YOU GUYS WANT TO DO.
>> I'M GOING TO INTRODUCE IN THE
SENATE AND THE SAME BILL WILL BE
INTRODUCED IN THE HOUSE, A BILL
TO BAN ASSAULT WEAPONS.
>> THE RESPONSE FROM DEFENDERS
OF THE SECOND AMENDMENT HAS BEEN
SOMEWHAT MUTED IN THE IMMEDIATE
AFTERMATH, BUT SOME POINT OUT
THAT GUNS ARE JUST ONE PART OF
THE EQUATION HERE.
ONE OTHER FREQUENT COMPONENT OF
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS IS MENTAL
ILLNESS AND HOW THE NATION DEALS
WITH THE MENTALLY ILL WILL NO
DOUBT BE PART OF THE
CONVERSATION.
>> WE ALSO HAVE TO DEAL WITH THE
NEW SOCIAL RAMIFICATIONS OF THE
BOMBARDMENT AND THE IMMEDIACY OF
SOCIAL INTERACTION BETWEEN
VIOLENCE, THE REALISM THAT YOU
FIND IN GAMES AND MOVIES.
MAKING THIS TRANSITIONPEOPLE AS
FROM TEEN YEARS INTO ADULTHOOD
AREN'T ABLE TO MENTALLY MAKE
THAT TRANSEXCISION THERE DOES
NEED TO BE HELP AND WE ALSO NEED
TO LOOK TO FAMILIES AND
COMMUNITIES AND CHURCHES.
IT'S NOT JUST THE GOVERNMENT
SOLUTION.
>> THE OTHER ASPECT HOW DO YOU
IDENTIFY THESE INDIVIDUALS THAT
MAY BE NOT JUST A DANGER TO
THEMSELVES, BECAUSE DANGER TO
OTHER PEOPLE AS WELL?
THAT'S A TOUGH QUESTION.
THE SHOOTER IN THIS CASE
APPARENTLY DID NOT HAVE A
CRIMINAL RECORD.
BACK TO YOU GUYS.
>> Steve: DOUG LIVE IN DC, THANK
YOU.
>> Gretchen: WE HEARD JASON
CHAFFETZ TALK ABOUT CHURCH AND
THE RESPONSIBILITY THERE.
YESTERDAY I HAVE TO SAY AT MY
CHURCH IN CONNECTICUT, FIRST
PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH, PACKED,
PACKED.
PEOPLE PROBABLY COMING THERE FOR
HOPE.
I WANT TO SHOW THINK PICTURE
BECAUSE IT WAS PROBABLY ONE OF
THE MOST IMPORTANT CHURCH
SERVICES THAT I'VE EVER HAD THE
OPPORTUNITY TO ATTEND.
YOU CAN SEE ALL THE POINSETTIAS
FOR CHRISTMAS.
BUT THEN YOU SEE THE LIGHTS UP
THERE AT THE FRONT OF THE
CHURCH.
THOSE ARE 27 CANDLES THAT WERE
ALL LIT AS EACH NAME OF EACH
VICTIM, INCLUDING THE SHOOTER,
WAS NAMED BY ONE OF OUR
MINISTERS.
EARLIER BEFORE THE CHILDREN LEFT
THE SANCTUARY, THERE WAS A
CHILDREN'S SERMON IN WHICH THEY
TALKED ABOUT HOW IMPORTANT THE
LIGHT OF A CANDLE CAN BE IN THE
LIFE OF A CHILD IF YOU HAVE THE
OPPORTUNITY TO BELIEVE IN
CHRISTIANITY.
THEN THE CHILDREN LEFT THE
SERVICE.
I WAS WONDERING WOULD THE
MINISTER TALK A LOT ABOUT THE
SHOOTING.
HE HAD AN AMAZING SERMON WHERE
HE SAID THAT AS A MAN OF GOD
AFTER ALL OF THESE YEARS, THAT
HE WAS INTELLECTUALLY EMPTY AND
VACANT AS TO HOW HE COULD
RESPOND TO WHAT HAPPENED IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
BUT I THINK THERE SHOULD BE A
DISCUSSION ABOUT GOD IN OUR
LIVES.
FOR ME, THIS IS ONE OF THE MOST
MOVING DAYS OF MY LIFE
YESTERDAY, TO SEE THIS AND TO
HONOR ALL OF THESE VICTIMS IN
THAT WAY.
SO HOPEFULLY WHEN YOU ALL WENT
TO CHURCH, IF YOU HAD THAT
OPPORTUNITY YESTERDAY, YOU HAD
THE OPPORTUNITY TO FIND SOME
HOPE IN YOUR LIFE AS WELL.
NOW TO THE REST OF TODAY'S HEAD
LYNNS.
A MANHUNT UNDERWAY FOR THE
GUNMAN WHO SHOT AND KILLED TWO
TOPEKA POLICE OFFICERS.
COPS ARE LOOK FOR THIS MAN.
22-YEAR-OLD DAVID TUSCARENO.
HE OPENED FIRES ON THE OFFICERS
OUTSIDE OF A GROCERY STORE AS
THEY WERE RESPONDING TO A CALL.
THE OFFICERS KILLED WERE A
50-YEAR-OLD CORPORAL DAVID
GOGIAN WHO RECENTLY RETIRED FROM
THE MILITARY.
HIS SON IS A TOPEKA POLICE
OFFICER AND 29-YEAR-OLD JEFF
ATTARLY.
HE HAD JUST JOINED THE FORCE
LAST YEAR.
>>> THE MOST DETAILED REPORT ON
THE BENGHAZI TERRORIST ATTACK
RELOOSED TODAY.
THE INDEPENDENT ADVISORY REVIEW
BOARD WILL DELIVER ITS
ASSESSMENT TO THE STATE
DEPARTMENT.
CONGRESS WILL SEE IT.
THE STATE DEPARTMENT WILL MAKE
RECOMMENDATIONS ON IMPROVING
SECURITY.
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON ORDERED THIS REVIEW.
SHE'S NOT TESTIFYING ABOUT
BENGHAZI THIS THURSDAY AFTER
FAINTING AND SUFFERING A
CONCUSSION.
>>> BRAND-NEW VIDEO SHOWING THE
AFTERMATH OF AN OVERNIGHT BOMB
BLAST IN KABUL, AFGHANISTAN.
TWO AFGHAN WORKERS DIED IN THIS
ATTACK OUTSIDE A COMPOUND
HOUSING U.S. MILITARY
CONTRACTOR.
DOZENS LEFT INJURED, INCLUDING
THE AMERICAN DIRECTOR OF THE
VIRGINIA-BASED COMPANY
CONTRACTS.
SPOKESPERSON FOR THE TALIBAN
CLAIMED RESPONSIBILITY FOR THIS
ATTACK.
>>> A GROUP OF SOLDIERS WEREN'T
SCHEDULED TO COME HOME UNTIL
JANUARY FROM AFGHANISTAN.
BUT WE NEED A GOOD NEWS STORY.
LET'S LOOK AT THIS CHRISTMAS
MIRACLE.
(
[ CHEERING ]
NINE ARMY SOLDIERS FROM THE 4505
CIVIL AFFAIRS BATTALION COMING
THOME SALT LAKE CITY, UTAH --
HOME TO SALT LAKE CITY.
>> THEY'RE THE ONES  THAT HAVE
TO DEAL WITH SOME REALLY HARD
TIMES.
>> HE'S OVER AND BACK.
EVERYTHING IS GOOD.
NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENED,
>> Gretchen: THE SOLDIERS HAD
BEEN IN AFGHANISTAN FOR NEARLY A
YEAR HELPING WITH RECONSTRUCTION
OF THE COUNTRY AND COMMUNICATION
WITH THE CIVILIANS THERE.
THOSE ARE YOUR HEADLINES.
>> Steve: NICE STORY.
STRAIGHT AHEAD, HE KNOWS THE
PAIN IN NEWTOWN ALL TOO WELL.
THE PRINCIPAL WHO LED STUDENTS
AND STAFF THROUGH THE COLUMBINE
TRAGEDY JOINS US LIVE NEXT FROM
DENVER.
>> Gretchen: REMEMBER WHEN THE
GOVERNMENT PUT ASIDE BILLIONS OF
DOLLARS TO HELP VICTIMS OF
HURRICANE SANDY?
WAIT UNTIL YOU HEAR WHERE SOME
OF THAT MONEY IS REALLY GOING
NOW
♪ THE WEATHER OUTSIDE
IS FRIGHTFUL ♪
♪ BUT THE FIRE IS
SO DELIGHTFUL ♪
NOTHING MELTS AWAY THE COLD
LIKE A HOT, DELICIOUS BOWL
OF CHICKEN NOODLE SOUP
FROM CAMPBELL'S.
♪ LET IT SNOW, LET IT SNOW
It's hard to see opportunity
in today's challenging
environment.
Unless you have the right
perspective.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
has the vision
and experience to look beyond
the obvious.
We'll uncover opportunities,
find hidden risk,
and make success a reality.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
NESPRESSO.
WHERE I NEVER HAVE TO COMPROMISE
ON ANYTHING.
♪
WHERE JUST ONE TOUCH
CREATES THE PERFECT COFFEE.
HE
>> Brian: SADLY THE SCHOOL
MASSACRE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY WAS NOT OUR NATION'S
FIRST.
IT HAPPENED SEVERAL YEARS
BEFORE, SEVERAL TIMES BEFORE.
>> Steve: INDEED.
ASK MY PARENTS WHO LOST THEIR
CHILD AT COLUMBINE HIGH SCHOOL
NEARLY 14 YEARS AGO.
THAT PAIN FROM THAT DAY HAS
NEVER GONE AWAY.
THE MAN WHO LED HIS STUDENTS AND
STAFF THROUGH THE COLUMBINE
TRAGEDY, PRINCIPAL FRANK
DEANGULUS, STILL LEADS THAT
SCHOOL TODAY AND JOINS US LIVE
IF COLORADO.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
>> GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
>> Steve: WHEN YOU HEARD THE
NEWS FRIDAY WHAT, DID YOU THINK?
>> NOT AGAIN.
GOT SICK TO MY STOMACH AND AS
DETAILS CAME IN, I THINK
EVERYBODY IN THE COLUMBINE
COMMUNITY WAS RETRAUMATIZED
BECAUSE WHAT HAPPENED, EVEN
THOUGH IT'S BEEN 14 YEARS AGO.
>> Steve: YEAH.
>> Brian: DOES IT SHOW US THAT
WE DIDN'T LEARN ANYTHING FROM
WHAT YOU GUYS WENT THROUGH OR
DOES IT SHOW THAT SOME OF THE
SECURITY MEASURES IN PLACE SHOW
THERE IS MORE OF A GENERAL
AWARENESS NOW BECAUSE OF YOUR
TRAGEDY OF YOU GUYS?
>> I THINK THERE WERE LESSONS
LEARNED.
IT WAS MY HOPE AFTER APRIL 20,
1999, THAT THE STUDENTS WHO LOST
THEIR LIFE AND THE TEACHER WHO
LOST HIS LIFE AT COLUMBINE HIGH
SCHOOL WOULD NOT DIE IN VAIN.
I KNOW THERE HAVE BEEN SECURITY
MEASURES THAT WERE IMCOMPLETED
AS A RESULT OF COLUMBINE HIGH
SCHOOL.
BUT AS A RESULT OF SOME OF THE
NEW PROCEDURES IN PLACE, I THINK
THERE HAVE BEEN SEVERAL
INSTANCES SINCE COLUMBINE THAT
WERE STOPPED AS A RESULT OF A
HEIGHTENED AWARENESS OF SCHOOL
VIOLENCE.
>> Steve: IT SOUNDS LIKE THEY
HAD DONE SO MANY OF THE RIGHT
THINGS, INSTALLED THE BUZZER AT
THE DOOR, THE DOOR WAS LOCKED.
BUT THE GUY BLEW THE WINDOW OUT
BUT SOMEHOW GOT IN AND THAT LED
TO WHERE WE ARE NOW.
FRANK, YOU KNOW, YOU'VE BEEN
THROUGH THIS, THERE ARE GOING TO
BE CALLS ON CAPITOL HILL,
ALTHOUGH TODAY NOT APPROPRIATE,
FOR MORE GUN CONTROL.
BUT WHEN YOU LOOK AT DYLAN
KLEBOLD AND ERIK HARRIS, IT
WASN'T JUST ABOUT GUNS.
>> I GET ASKED THAT FREQUENTLY
WHEN TRAGEDIES OCCUR, WHETHER IT
BE AT VIRGINIA TECH OR OHIO.
I TRULY BELIEVE WHAT NEEDS TO BE
DONE IS MONEY NEEDS TO BE SPENT
TO FIGURE OUT WHAT IS CAUSING SO
MUCH HATE IN THE HEART OF THESE
MURDERS, WHAT CAUSED SO MUCH
HATE IN THE HEARTS OF THE TWO AT
COLUMBINE OR THE KILLER UP AT
VIRGINIA TECH?
THAT'S WHERE MONEY NEEDS TO BE
SPENT.
THESE KIDS ARE CRYING OUT.
THEY DO NOT COME OUT OF THEIR
MOTHER'S WOMB HATING PEOPLE.
SO I THINK SCHOOLS AND PROGRAMS
NEED TO BE DEVELOPED TO FIGURE
OUT WHAT IS CAUSING HATE TO
PROVIDE HELP THAT THESE
MURDERERS ARE CRYING OUT FOR.
>> Brian: SOME OF THEM CANNOT BE
IN THE MAIN STREAM.
WE PULLED AWAY FROM THAT, BUT WE
GOT TO THINK ABOUT OTHER PEOPLE
OF THE PRINCIPAL, YOU WALKED
INTO A HAIL OF GUN FIRE THAT
DAY.
YOU EXPERIENCED PTSD.
DO YOU SUSPECT SOME PEOPLE AT
SANDY HOOK WILL HAVE THE SAME
THING?
>> MOST DEFINITELY.
THE THING I FOUND OUT ABOUT
PTSD, NO ONE CAN PREDICT WHEN IT
WILL HAPPEN.
AT COLUMBINE, THERE WERE SEVERAL
THAT EXPERIENCED IT IMMEDIATELY
I. EXPERIENCED IT IMMEDIATELY.
WHAT I NOTICED OVER THE YEARS,
WE HAD SOME TEACHERS THAT WERE
DOING VERY WELL AND ALL OF A
SUDDEN, AT THE TEN-YEAR
ANNIVERSARY OF THE COLUMBINE
TRAGEDY, THEY STARTED
EXPERIENCING PTSD.
SO IT'S UNPREDICTABLE WHEN IT'S
GOING TO OCCUR.
BUT ANY TIME A TRAGEDY DOES
OCCUR SUCH AS WHAT HAPPENED ON
FRIDAY, IT DOES TRAUMATIZE
PEOPLE, TRIGGERS ARE SET OFF.
BUT IT'S SOMETHING TO DEAL WITH.
FORTUNATELY FOR ME, I WAS TOLD
BAY CLOSE FRIEND OF THE FAMILY
THE DAY AFTER, IF I WAS GOING TO
HELP OTHERS, I HAD TO HELP
MYSELF.
I GOT INTO COUNSELING
IMMEDIATELY AND NOT THAT PTSD
WILL GO AWAY, BUT AT LEAST I
KNOW HOW TO COPE WITH THE
SYMPTOMS.
>> Steve: I'M SURE THAT LOT OF
FOLKS IN NEWTOWN WILL FOLLOW
YOUR ADVICE AND YOUR LEADERSHIP.
ALL RIGHT.
FRANK, PRINCIPAL OF COLUMBINE,
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Brian: STORY WAS BROKEN RIGHT
HERE ON "FOX & FRIENDS."
YOU HAVE A FORMER MARINE BEING
HELD FOR MONTHS IN MEXICO ON
TRUMPED UP CHARGES.
HIS MOM JUST SPOKE WITH HIM.
SHE WILL JOIN US LIVE RIGHT
AFTER THE BREAK.
>> Steve: THEN HE WORKED YEARS
TO BUILD HIS SMALL BUSINESS AND
IT WAS DESTROYED IN MINUTES BY
ANGRY UNION PROTESTERS.
YOU GOT TO HEAR WHAT HAPPENED TO
HIM NEXT
add up to 100 calories?
Your world.
♪
[ whispers ]
Real bacon...
Creamy cheese...
100 calories...
[ Chef ] Ma'am
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME R CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
Meet the 5-passenger
Ford C-MAX Hybrid.
BY DECEMBER 22ND
When you're carrying
a lot of weight,
C-MAX has a nice little trait,
You see, C-MAX helps
you load your freight,
with its foot-activated
lift gate.
But that's not
all you'll see,
Cause C-MAX also
beats Prius v,
with better MPG.
Say hi to the all-new 47
combined MPG C-MAX Hybrid.
>> Gretchen: HE FOUGHT FOR HIS
COUNTRY IN IRAQ AND AFGHANISTAN.
NOW HE'S FIGHTING FOR HIS OWN
FREEDOM.
FORMER MARINE JON HAMMMAR LOCKED
UP IN A MEXICAN PRISON WHERE
HE'S BEEN HELD FOR FOUR MONTHS
FOR POSSESSION OF A REGISTERED
ANTIQUE WEAPON.
HE'S REPORTEDLY BEING HELD THERE
BY MEMBERS OF A MEXICAN CARTEL
WHO ARE THREATEN TO GO KILL HIM
UNLESS THEY GET PAID.
LAWMAKERS ARE STARTING TO STEP
IN.
WILL THE FAMILY SEE THEIR SON IN
TIME FOR CHRISTMAS?
JOHN'S MOTHER, OLIVIA, JOINS ME
LIVE FROM MIAMI.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
>> GOOD MORNING, THANK YOU FOR
HAVING ME.
>> Gretchen: OF COURSE.
WE TALKED TO YOU MAYBE A FEW
WEEKS AGO WHEN YOU FIRST DECIDED
TO GO PUBLIC WITH THIS STORY.
WHAT'S THE LATEST?
WHAT HAVE YOU HEARD FROM YOUR
SON?
>> I THINK HE IS -- IT'S
BECOMING MORE TENUOUS EVERY DAY.
I THINK THE SITUATION IS MORE
DIRE AS BECOMES MORE AND MORE
PUBLIC.
I KNOW THAT THE STORY HAS GONE
IN SOME OF THE TOP PAPERS IN
MEXICO CITY AND IT'S CERTAINLY
ALL OVER THE BORDER TOWNS AND
THE PAPERS AND HE'S GETTING
FEEDBACK, WHY ARE YOU IN THE
NEWS?
WHAT'S THIS ALL ABOUT?
WHY DOESN'T YOUR FAMILY JUST
PAY?
SO THAT'S SORT OF THE FEEDBACK
HE'S GETTING AND IT'S NERVE
RACKING.
>> Gretchen: IT'S MY
UNDERSTANDING THAT THESE CARTELS
RUN SOME OF THE PRISONS IN
MEXICO AND THEY HAD BEEN IN
TOUCH WITH YOU AND THEY ARE
DEMANDING SOME SORT OF A RANSOM?
>> THEY DID IN THE VERY
BEGINNING.
THE CONSUL GOT INVOLVED AND ABLE
TO ISOLATE HIM AND THOSE CALLS
STOPPED.
SO WE HAVEN'T HAD TO DEAL WITH
THAT ANYMORE.
BUT 90% OF THAT PRISON IS IN
THIS GENERAL POPULATION THAT IS
CONTROLLED, EVERY ASPECT OF THE
GENERAL POPULATION IS CONTROLLED
BY THE CARTEL.
MOST OF THE GUARDS WON'T EVEN
ENTER INTO THAT SECTION OF THE
PRISON.
>> Gretchen: HOW IS HE BEING
TREATED?
WE HAD HEARD REPORTS THAT I
THINK HE TOLD YOU DIRECTLY HE
WAS BEING CHAIN TO DO A BED.
>> EXACTLY.
I THINK IN THE LAST COUPLE OF
DAYS THEY HAVE REMOVED THOSE
CHAINS JUST BECAUSE OF THE
PUBLICITY.
I THINK THEY TEND TO PUT THEM ON
WHEN VISITING HOURS ARE OVER,
BECAUSE THERE ARE VISITING HOURS
AND BECAUSE OF WHERE HE'S
LOCATED IN THE PRISON, PEOPLE
ARE CONSTANTLY WALKING BY THERE
AND CAN SEE HIM.
SO HE HAS A HIGH VISIBILITY.
>> Gretchen: INTERESTING THAT
THIS PUBLICITY MAY HAVE HELPED.
I KNOW IT WAS A BIG RISK.
I WANT YOU TO LISTEN TO A
CONGRESSWOMAN IN FLORIDA WHO IS
WORKING DILIGENTLY ON YOUR
BEHALF.
I INTERVIEWED HER LAST WEEK.
>> THIS IS UNBELIEVABLE THAT THE
MEXICAN GOVERNMENT IS NOT
STEPPING IN TO HELP US WHILE
THEY TAKE OUR MONEY AND TAKE ALL
THE HELP WE GIVE THEM.
IT'S INCREDIBLE THAT OUR OWN
U.S. GOVERNMENT IS NOT DOING ALL
THAT WE CAN TO BRING HIM HOME
FOR CHRISTMAS.
THE FAMILY DESERVES THIS.
HE'S DONE NOTHING WRONG.
IT IS SO UNFAIR AND SO UNJUST,
SO WE'RE GOING TO KEEP ON
FIGHTING AND MAKE THIS HAPPEN.
>> Gretchen: I WANT TO MENTION
THAT SENATOR NELSON AND CUBE I
DON'T ALSO WORKING ON YOUR --
RUBIO ALSO WORKING ON YOUR
BEHALF IN FLORIDA.
OLIVIA, DO YOU THINK YOU'RE
GOING TO SEE YOUR SON IN TIME
FOR CHRISTMAS?
>> YOU KNOW, WE'RE TRYING NOT TO
GET OUR HOPES UP OR JOHN'S HOPES
UP BECAUSE IT'S JUST SO
DEFLATING WHEN NOTHING HAPPENS.
AT THIS POINT WE'RE BEGGING THE
MEXICAN GOVERNMENT, FIRST OF
ALL, TO LOOK AT THIS CASE.
IF THEY WILL JUST EXAMINE THIS
CASE.
THEIR OWN MILITARY HAS SENT A
LETTER SAYING THIS GUN IS NOT ON
THE RESTRICTED LIST.
I'M ASKING THAT THE MEXICAN
GOVERNMENT WOULD USE PROSECUTIAL
POWER TO LOOK AT IT AND LET HIM
GO BECAUSE HE'S TOTALLY INNOCENT
OF THE CRIME HE'S BEEN CHARGED
WITH.
>> Gretchen: OLIVIA HAMMAR, A
MOM IN PAIN AND HOPING HER SON
CAN BE HOME BEFORE CHRISTMAS.
THANKS.
WE'LL CONTINUE O FOLLOW THIS
STORY.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> Gretchen: BRAND-NEW
INFORMATION JUST COMING IN ABOUT
ADAM LAZY -- LANZA AND HIS
MOTHER.
THE MOTHER'S CONFIDANTE AND HIS
FIRST TV INTERVIEW NEXT.
>>> THE GOVERNMENT PUT ASIDE
BILLIONS TO HELP SANDY VICTIMS.
YOU'LL HEAR WHERE SOME OF THE
MONEY IS ACTUALLY GOING.
HOW ABOUT ALASKA
casting line,
marching band playing ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THE RHYTHM OF LIFE.
[ whistle blowing ]
WHERE DO YOU HEAR THAT BEAT?
CAMPBELL'S HEALTHY REQUEST SOUP
LETS YOU HEAR IT...
IN YOUR HEART.
[ basketball bouncing ]
HEART HEALTHY.
GREAT TASTE.
MMM...
[ Male Announcer ] SOUNDS GOOD.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
ADVIL PM® OR TYLENOL PM.
THE ADVIL PM® GUY
IS SPENDING LESS TIME
LYING AWAKE
WITH ANNOYING ACHES AND PAINS
AND MORE TIME ASLEEP.
ADVIL PM®. THE DIFFERENCE
IS A BETTER NIGHT'S SLEEP.
AND WITH MY BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CREDIT CARD,
I LOVE 'EM EVEN MORE.
I EARN 1% CASH BACK EVERYWHERE,
EVERTIME.
2% ON GROCERIES.
3% ON GAS.
AUTOMATICALLY.
NO HOOPS TO JUMP THROUGH.
THAT'S 1% BACK ON...
[ toy robot sounds ]
2% ON PUMPN PIE.
AND APPLE.
3% BACK ON 4 TRIPS
TO THE AIRPORT.
IT'S AS EASY AS..
-[ man ] 1...
-[ woman ] 2...
[ woman ] 3.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CARD.
APPLY ONLINE OR AT
A BANK OF AMERICA NEAR YOU.
>> Gretchen: WELCOME BACK.
THE NATION AND THE WORLD
GRIEVING FOR THE TRAGEDY IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
NEW YORK CITY'S TIMES SQUARE
FULL OF PEOPLE HOLING CANDLES
AND SIGNS.
FLAGS FLOWN AT HALF-STAFF AT THE
U.S. EMBASSY IN ROME, ITALY.
WITH CROSSES LINING THE BEACH IN
RIO DE JANIERO.
MOURNERS LAYING FLOWERS IN THE
SAND.
IN PAKISTAN, CHILDREN SENDING
MESSAGES OF COMPASSION, LIGHTING
CANDLES ON THE STREETS IN
TRIBUTE.
>> Steve: THAT'S NICE.
MEANWHILE, BRAND-NEW INFORMATION
JUST COMING IN ABOUT ADAM LANZA
AND HIS MOTHER, NANCY.
WHAT HAPPENED BEFORE HE WENT ON
A KILLING SPREE?
PEOPLE DOOCY JUST PEOPLE WITH A
CONFIDENTANT, A FRIEND OF NANCY
LANZA AND JOINS US.
>> I MET RICH COLLINS LAST NIGHT
AT A RESTAURANT CALLED MY PLACE
IN NEWTOWN, WHICH WAS ONE OF
NANCY LANZA'S FAVORITE PLACES TO
GO FORTUNER AND DRINKS.
RICH TOLD ME THAT SINCE HE HAS A
SON WITH AUTISM AND NANCY HAD A
SON, A ASBURGERS, THEY WOULD
BOND SOMETIMES ABOUT THE
DIFFICULTIES SOMETIMES IN
DEALING WITH THAT.
LISTEN TO WHAT HE TOLD ME.
>> NANCY WOULD GET UPSET BECAUSE
HER SON REFUSED TO LET HER TOUCH
HIM.
SHE COULDN'T HUG HIM.
MY SON IS JUST THE OPPOSITE.
SHE'D SEE MY SON HANGING ALL
OVER ME.
BUT AUTISTIC KIDS, EACH AND
EVERY ONE OF THEM IS DIFFERENT.
>> YOU SAID THAT THERE WERE
DIFFERENT THINGS THAT SHE TRIED
TO DO BECAUSE SHE HAD A HARD
TIME BONDING WITH HIM?
>> YEAH.
SHE WAS TRYING TO BOND, FIND
WAYS TO BOND WITH HIM.
SHE TOLD ME THE GUNS, SHE WOULD
TAKE THEM SHOOTING BECAUSE THAT
WAS A WAY THAT A SINGLE MOM
COULD RELATE TO HER SON.
>> RICH COLLINS ALSO TOLD ME
THAT HE THINKS NANCY LANZA DID
THE BEST SHE COULD, BUT THAT SHE
DID NOT HAVE BEING A SINGLE
MOTHER, THE SUPPORT SYSTEM
NECESSARY FOR DEALING WITH
SOMEONE LOUISORORER -- LIKE
ADAM.
THEY'RE SAYING HE FIRED SEVERAL
HUNDRED SHOTS INSIDE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AROUND HERE, THERE IS VERY
LITTLE FOCUS, SPECIFIC FOCUS ON
ADAM LANZA.
THERE IS MUCH MORE FOCUS INSTEAD
ON THE NAMES OF HIS VICTIMS THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA READ ONE AT A
TIME LAST NIGHT.
BACK TO YOU IN NEW YORK.
>> Steve: THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> Brian: SHE DID NOT HAVE MAYBE
THE RESOURCES FAMILY WISE, BUT
SHE HAD IT FINANCIALLY.
>> Steve: SHE DID.
>> Brian: SHE WOULD BE ABLE
TO -- SHE HAD HEALTH INSURANCE
OR COULD AFFORD TO BUY HER OWN.
SO THERE WAS SOME ASPECTS TO IT.
I'M NOT QUESTIONING HER
DEDICATION TO IT.
BUT I JUST WONDER ABOUT THE
SANITY OF GIVING A KID THAT
COULD NOT SHOW AFFECTION OR FEEL
PAIN THE ABILITY TO SHOOT A GUN.
>> Gretchen: I AGREE WITH YOU
ON.
I WILL SAY THAT MENTAL ILLNESS
IN OUR SOCIETY IS REALLY,
REALLY, REALLY DIFFICULT TO GET
PEOPLE INTO INSTITUTIONS OR
HOSPITALS OR TO TAKE MEDICATION.
THE ACLU HAS FOUGHT HARD ABOUT
DOING JUST THAT AND THAT'S ONE
OF THE REASONS WHY WE HAVE SO
MANY OF THE HOMELESS PEOPLE ON
OUR STREETS WHO ARE MENTALLY
ILL.
THIS IS A HUGE NATIONAL
DISCUSSION NOW, EVEN TOUGH FOR A
MOM TO GET THEIR OWN KID HELP IN
MANY, MANY, MANY CASES.
>> Brian: A COURT CAN MANDATE
THAT YOU TAKE MEDICATION, WE
FOUND OUT OVER THE WEEKEND, EVEN
UNADULT TAKE MEDICATION IF
YOU'RE A DANGER TO SOCIETY.
>> Steve: WHY DID HE GO TO SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL?
THERE WERE STORIES FLOATING
AROUND THAT WE THINK HIS MOM WAS
AN AID OR VOLUNTEER.
SCHOOL SAYS THEY HAVE NO
CONNECTION.
THERE HE IS, THAT'S A PICTURE OF
HIM FROM THE TECH CLUB YEARBOOK.
INTERESTINGLY ENOUGH, ADAM LANZA
DID ACTUALLY GO NOT ONLY TO THE
HIGH SCHOOL WHERE THEY HAD THE
MEMORIAL LAST NIGHT, BUT HE ALSO
WENT TO THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WHAT MADE HIM SNAP?
>> Brian: WHY DID HE GO THERE?
>> Steve: WHY DID HE GO THERE?
ROD WHEELER, FORMER DETECTIVE IN
DC JOINED US EARLIER TO GIVE US
HIS OPINION OF WHAT MAY HAVE
HAPPENED INSIDE THE MAN.
>> I BELIEVE QUITE A FEW PEOPLE
IN THAT COMMUNITY WERE VERY
FAMILIAR WITH ADAM LANZA.
THE QUESTION IS WHY DID HE GO TO
THIS PARTICULAR SCHOOL?
I THINK SOMEONE AT THE SCHOOL
WAS FAMILIAR WITH HIM, TOO.
I THINK HE KILLED HIS MOTHER
BECAUSE I THINK HE PHYSICAL LIKE
HIS MOTHER BETRAYED HIM.
A PERSON THAT'S MENTALLY
UNSTABLE DOES NOT WANT TO BE
TOLD WHAT TO DO OR WHERE TO GO.
NOW, EVEN IF THE MOTHER WAS
TRYING TO GET THIS GUY PROBATED
THROUGH THE COURTS, IF THE
POLICE WOULD HAVE WENT TO GET
HIM, TRUST ME, THEY WOULD HAVE
TAKEN SEVERAL OFFICERS BECAUSE
HE WAS CLEARLY A DANGER.
HE WAS GOING DOWN THAT PATH.
HE WAS GOING DOWN THAT PATH VERY
QUICKLY, BUT I DON'T BELIEVE
THAT THEY THOUGHT AT ANY POINT
THAT HE WAS GOING TO TAKE IT TO
THIS LEVEL.
>> Steve: YEAH.
AND IN FACT, BEFORE FRIDAY, HE
HAD ABSOLUTELY NO DISCIPLINARY
PROBLEMS ON HIS RECORD, ALTHOUGH
THE SCHOOL AND MIDDLE SCHOOL DID
IDENTIFY HIM AS SOMEONE TO KEEP
AN EYE ON.
THEN IN HIGH SCHOOL, HE HAD A
PERMANENT PSYCHOLOGIST ASSIGNED
TO HIM THROUGHOUT HIS HIGH
SCHOOL CAREER, EVEN THOUGH HE
DROPPED OUT FOR HOME SCHOOLING.
THEY WERE WORRIED NOT OF
VIOLENCE, BUT THAT HE MIGHT
ACTUALLY BE THE VICTIM OF
SOMEBODY ELSE BULLYING HIM
BECAUSE HE WAS SO SOCIALLY
AWKWARD.
>> Gretchen: INTERESTING.
NOW TO THE REST OF YOUR
HEADLINE.
ONE DAY AFTER THE NEWTOWN
SHOOTING, A MAN UNDER ARREST FOR
THREATENING A DIFFERENT KIND OF
A SCHOOL MASSACRE.
THIS ONE IN INDIANA.
POLICE FOUND 47 GUNS INSIDE
VAUGHN MYERS' HOME, NEXT DOOR TO
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WHERE HIS
WIFE WORKS.
DURING A FIGHT, HE ALLEGEDLY
THREATENED TO SET HIS WIFE ON
FIRE, THEN SAID HE WOULD GO TO
THE SCHOOL AND KILL AS MANY
PEOPLE AS POSSIBLE.
>> Brian: OVERNIGHT, TWO POLICE
STATIONS IN BENGHAZI, LIBYA,
REMEMBER THOSE CITIES AND
REMEMBER THAT COUNTRY?
-- WERE TARGETED IN SIMULTANEOUS
ATTACKS.
AN EXPLOSIVE DEVICE WAS THROWN
OUT OF A PARKED CAR AT ONE
STATION AT THE SAME TIME A SMALL
BLAST WENT OFF AT ANOTHER POLICE
STATION, DAMAGING A WALL.
NO ONE WALES HURT IN EITHER
ATTACK.
>> Steve: MEANWHILE, AFTER A
TOUGH COUPLE OF WEEKS, KATE
MIDDLETON IS BACK IN THE
SPOTLIGHT.
HERE IS THE PREGNANT DUCHESS
BACK STAGE AT THE BBC SPORTS
PERSONALITY OF THE YEAR AWARD IN
LONDON WHERE SHE PRESENTED TWO
AWARDS.
EARLIER THIS MONTH, SHE WAS
HOSPITALIZED FOR SEVERE MORNING
SICKNESS.
SOURCES SAY SHE WASN'T FEELING
WELL ENOUGH TO STAY FOR THE
ENTIRE FOUR HOUR EVENT AND WENT
HOME AFTER 45 MINUTES.
SHE WAS THERE AND EVERYBODY
APPRECIATED IT.
>> Gretchen: AN UPDATE TO A
STORY WE'VE BEEN FOLLOWING ON
"FOX & FRIENDS."
LAST WEEK WE TOLD BUT CLINTON
TARVER, HE WORKED FOR FIVE YEARS
TO BUILD A SMALL BUSINESS IN
LANSING, MICHIGAN.
BUT IN A FEW MINUTES, UNION
WORKERS DESTROYED HIS CART N.
RESPONSE, SUPPORTERS CREATED AN
ON-LINE FUND-RAISER AND DONATED
MORE THAN $33,000.
HE SAYS HE PLANS TO USE THE
MONEY TO BUY A BRAND-NEW CART.
ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU FOR THAT SUPPORT.
>> Brian: THEY GOT TO SHE WILL
UP -- SHELL UP FOR A FEW TENTS.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU SAW THE
SUNDAY NIGHT FOOTBALL GAME, IF
DID YOU NOT, YOU MISSED THIS
TRIBUTE.
THEY PAID A TRIBUTE TO ALL 26
VICTIMS IN THE NEWTOWN TRAGEDY.
26 WHITE FLAIRS WERE SENT INTO
THE SKY DURING A MOMENT OF
SILENCE AND THEY PLEDGED $25,000
TO HELP THE FAMILIES OF THE
VICTIMS AS FORT GAME ITSELF, THE
49ERS GOT OFF TO A HUGE FIGHT
AND WITHSTOOD A 28-POINT
COMEBACK BY THE PATRIOTS.
THEN A TOUCHDOWN PASS.
THEY STAVED OFF THE PATRIOTS.
SAN FRANCISCO WON 41-34.
WHO IS GOING TO WIN THE NFC
EAST?
WE HAVE A THREE-WAY TIE.
KIRK COUSINS GOOD, TWO TOUCHDOWN
S.
WASHINGTON WINS AGAINST THE
BROWNS.
WHAT ABOUT THE COWBOYS?
NO WAY THEY'RE GOING TO BEAT THE
STEELERS.
WRONG.
ROETHLISBERGER FINDS THE WRONG
TEAM.
THE COWBOYS WIN AGAIN.
>>> AND THE GIANTS FANS, GIANTS
WERE THROTTLED BY THE FALCONS.
THE GIANTS LOST 34-0.
THEY HAD EMBLEMS ON EACH OF
THEIR HELMETS IN TRIBUTE TO
THOSE WHO LOST THEIR LIVES AND
VICTOR CRUZ IN PARTICULAR WORE
THE NAME OF THE ONE SIX-YEAR-OLD
CHILD THAT LOOKED UP TO HIM AND
IS GOING TO BE BURIED IN HIS
JERSEY.
>> Steve: THEY ALSO HAD EMBLEMS
FOR SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
LET'S GO FROM SANDY HOOK TO
HURRICANE SANDY.
THERE IS THE PRESIDENT WANTS
$60 BILLION TO HELP THE PEOPLE
THROUGHOUT THE NORTHEAST WHO
WERE IMPACTED EXTRAORDINARILY
ENOUGH IN THAT $60 BILLION BILL,
IT'S A PORK PROJECT.
HOW COULD ALASKA WIND UP WITH
$150 MILLION OUT OF THE SANDY
SCAM FOR FAIR FISHERIES?
>> GITMO, MAYBE THEY NEED
ANOTHER SOCCER FIELD.
5.2 MILLION FOR THE JUSTICE
DEPARTMENT.
4 MILLION TO KENNEDY SPACE
CENTER IN FLORIDA.
3.5 MILLION FOR HOMELAND
SECURITY.
2 MILLION FOR SMITHSONIAN
INSTITUTION IN D.C
CAN'T YOU JUST LOOK AT ONE
TRAGEDY, AS IF WE HAVEN'T HAD
ENOUGH.
CAN'T WE JUST LOOK AT ONE
TRAGEDY AND SAY, HEY, THOSE
PEOPLE ARE SUFFERING.
THEY ACTUALLY NEED THE
$60 BILLION.
WHY DOES IT ALWAYS HAVE TO COME
DOWN TO POLITICS WHERE NOW
PEOPLE ARE RAISING THEIR HANDS
AND SAYING, WE'LL NEED 2, 2, 2?
>> Brian: IT'S UP TO GUYS LIKE
SENATOR HUMANER AND GILLIBRAND
TO SAY I'M OUTRAGED BY MY
COLLEAGUES  THAT WOULD DO THAT
FOR THEIR STATE WHEN THEY WERE
NOT AFFECTED BY A SUPER STORM.
>> Steve: GET ALL THE MONEY AND
MAKE SURE IT GOES TO THE PEOPLE
IMPACTED.
STRAIGHT AHEAD, IN THE WAKE OF
NEWTOWN, MANY ARE WONDERING WHAT
IS HAPPENING TO THE CULTURE OF
THE UNITED STATES?
GOVERNOR MIKE HUCKABEE SAYS WE
NEED TO START GETTING BACK TO
PRAYER.
HE'S GOING TO JOIN US LIVE.
>> Gretchen: SUSAN RICE IS OUT.
JOHN KERRY IS IN.
WHAT COULD THAT MEAN FOR THE
BALANCE OF POWER IN CONGRESS?
SECRETARY OF STATE, IT COULD BE
TRICKY
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a
Droid Incredible 4G LTE
by HTC for $49.99.
NESPRESSO.
WHERE I NEVER HAVE TO COMPROMISE
ON ANYTHING.
♪
WHERE JUST ONE TOUCH
CREATES THE PERFECT COFFEE.
WHERE EVERY CAPPUCCINO AND LATTE
IS ONLY MADE WITH FRESH MILK.
AND WHERE THE STAFF
IS EXCEPTIONALLY FRIENDLY.
♪
NESPRESSO. WHAT ELSE?
TRY RUNNING FOUR.NING
A RESTAURANT IS HARD,
FORTUNATELY WE'VE GOT INK.
IT GIVES US 5X THE REWARDS
ON OUR INTERNET, PHONE
CHARGES AND CABLE,
PLUS AT OFFICE SUPPLY STORES.
REWARDS WE PUT RIGHT
BACK INTO OUR BUSINESS.
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
WE'VE EVER WANTED TO DO
AND INK HELPS US DO IT.
MAKE YOUR MARK
WITH INK FROM CHASE.
>> Brian: WELCOME BACK.
WITH SUSAN RICE OUT OF THE
RUNNING FOR SECRETARY OF STATE,
ALL EYES ARE FOCUSED ON JOHN
KERRY.
WORD IS THE 69-YEAR-OLD
MASSACHUSETTS SENATOR AND FORMER
DEMOCRATIC PRESIDENTIAL
CANDIDATE IS SET TO BE
NOMINATED.
SO WHAT WOULD THAT MEAN FOR THE
STATE DEPARTMENT?
WHAT WOULD THE STATE DEPARTMENT
LOOK UNDER KERRY AND WHAT
HAPPENS TO HIS SENATE SEAT?
KELLY CARD -- FIRST OFF, SENATOR
KERRY IS SECRETARY OF STATE.
WHAT DOES HE BRING TO THE TABLE?
WHO WHAT WILL THE STATE
DEPARTMENT LOOK LIKE UNDER HIM?
>> BRIAN, HE DOES KNOW A LOT OF
PEOPLE.
HE'S BEEN IN THE SENATE FOR A
LONG TIME AND ALWAYS INTERESTED
IN FOREIGN POLICY.
THAT'S THE PLUS SIDE.
ON THE DOWN SIDE, HE'S ALL BEEN
RATHER INDECISIVE AS A
POLITICIAN.
WE ALL REMEMBER THE LINE FROM
THE 2004 CAMPAIGN, I VOTED FOR
THE 87 BILLION BEFORE
AGAINST IT.
DURING THE FIRST GULF WAR, HE
SENT ONE CONSTITUENT TWO
SEPARATE LETTERS.
THE FIRST LETTER HE SAID HE WAS
FOR THE WAR AND THE SECOND ONE
SAID HE WASN'T.
IF HE COULD TAKE ORDERS, HE
SHOULD BE OKAY.
BUT ANOTHER NEGATIVE IS THAT
HE'S A RATHER QUESTIONABLE JUDGE
OF CHARACTER.
HE PINTED JOHN EDWARDS TO BE HIS
RUNNING MATE IN 2004 AND HE
GUSHED OVER BASHIR AL ASSAD.
HE'S BEEN SILENT EVER SINCE
ABOUT WHAT'S GOING ON IN SYRIA.
>> Brian: THE PRESIDENT HAS BEEN
HANDS OFF WITH THE STATE
DEPARTMENT B. WHO KNOWS.
LET'S TALK ABOUT THE SENATE SEAT
HE WOULD LEAVE BEHIND.
THEY HAVE 160 DAYS TO FILL IT.
SCOTT BROWN LOST BY EIGHT.
BUT SCOTT BROWN FAVORABLES IN
MASSACHUSETTS WERE VERY HIGH.
>> RIGHT.
WHAT HAPPENED IS THAT HE WAS
ELECTED TO REPLACE TED KENNEDY
IN A UNIQUE JANUARY ELECTION.
THERE WERE ONLY 2.2 MILLION
VOTERS TURNED U. THIS PAST
NOVEMBER WAS A PRESIDENTIAL
YEAR.
EXTRA MILLION VOTERS TURNED OUT.
THOSE ARE THE PEOPLE RUSH CALLS
LOW INFORMATION VOTERS.
HE BROWN GOT 350,000 MORE VOTES,
BUT GOT SWAMPED BY ELIZABETH
WARREN.
NIECE PRETTY GOOD SHAPE, UNLESS
THE GOVERNOR APPOINTS SOMEBODY
AND THERE IS NO PRIMARY.
WHAT SCOTT NEEDS IS A DIVISIVE
DEMOCRATIC PRIMARY LIKE HE GOT
IN 2009 AFTER TED KENNEDY'S
DEATH.
>> Brian: YOU SAID YOU SPOKE TO
HIM LAST NIGHT.
WHAT DOES HE SEE AS A SCENARIO
THAT COULD HAPPEN, 'CAUSE PEOPLE
ARE TALK BEING VICKY KENNEDY,
TED KENNEDY'S WIDOW, MAYBE
PATRICK PICKING HIMSELF TO RUN.
>> I DON'T THINK THAT DuVAL
WILL PICK HIMSELF.
HE'S BEEN CLEAR ABOUT THAT.
PEOPLE SPECULATED THAT SHE WOULD
BE THE INTERIM SENATOR UNTIL THE
PRIMARY COULD BE HELD TO PICK
SOMEBODY TO RUN AGAINST SCOTT IN
MAY OR JUNE.
BUT I THINK WHAT SCOTT AND
REPUBLICANS ARE CONCERNED ABOUT
IS DUVAL MAY TELL VICKY KENNEDY
THAT SHE OR SOMEONE ELSE, BUT
PROBABLY VICKY KENNEDY, THAT SHE
COULD RUN IN THE PRIMARY TO FILL
THE REMAINING TWO YEARS OF
KERRY'S TERM AND IF THE
DEMOCRATS DON'T HAVE A BLOOD
BATH, IT'S GOING TO BE MUCH MORE
DIFFICULT FOR SCOTT BROWN TO WIN
IN A GENERAL ELECTION, A SPECIAL
ELECTION.
>> Brian: WOW.
HE SEEMS TO HAVE DONE SUCH A
GOOD JOB.
THANKS SO MUCH.
APPRECIATE THE INSIDE BALL ON
MASSACHUSETTS.
ALWAYS GO TO SEE YOU.
>> THANK YOU, BRIAN.
ALWAYS A PLEASURE.
>> Brian: COMING UP STRAIGHT
AHEAD, IN THE WAKE OF THE
NEWTOWN SHOOTING, WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT SCHOOL SECURITY.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT GUN CONTROL.
WE ALSO NEED TO TALK ABOUT THE
CULTURE IN THIS COUNTRY.
ARE WE HEADING IN THE WRONG
DIRECTION?
DO WE NEED TO GO BACK TO PRAYER?
GOVERNOR HUCKABEE THINKS SO.
WE'LL TALK MORE ABOUT THAT NEXT
[ Male Announcer ]
IN BLIND TASTE TESTS,
EVEN RAGU USERS CHOSE PREGO.
PREGO?!
BUT I'VE BOUGHT RAGU FOR YEARS.
[ Thinking ] WONDER WHAT OTHER
QUESTIONABLE CHOICES I'VE MADE?
I CHOOSE DATE NUMBER 2!
WHOOO!
[ sigh of relief ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHOOSE TASTE. CHOOSE PREGO.
FIVE DAYS LATER,
I HAD A MASSIVE HEART ATTACK.
BAYER ASPIRIN WAS THE FIRST
THING THE EMTS GAVE ME.
NOW, I'M ON
A BAYER ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Male Announcer ] BE SURE
TO TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE YOU BEGIN
AN ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Woman ]
LEARN FROM MY STORY.
>> Gretchen: WELCOME BACK.
SO WE'RE GOING TO BRING YOU MORE
HARROWING STORIES NOW, GOOD NEWS
THAT HAS COME OUT OF THE
HORRIBLE NEWS IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THE SCHOOL NURSE WHO WAS ABLE TO
SURVIVE.
WHY?
BECAUSE SHE HAD THE WHEREWITHAL
GOING UNDERNEATH HER DESK AND
EVENTUALLY INTO A CLOSET WITH
ANOTHER ONE OF THE EMPLOYEES
FROM THE SCHOOL.
SHE WAS INTERVIEWED LAST NIGHT
JUST ABOUT HOW LONG SHE WAS IN
THIS CLOSET AND WHETHER OR NOT
SHE BELIEVED THAT IT WAS
ACTUALLY THE REAL POLICE WHO
WERE THERE TO FINALLY SAVE HER.
>> YOU KNOW, IT WAS THIS
HORRIBLE FEELING, YOU KNOW.
JUST LIKE A NIGHTMARE THAT --
COULDN'T BELIEVE THAT, YOU
KNOW -- IT'S AD ABOUT DREAM.
AFTER SOME TIME, I THINK IT WAS
ABOUT 11:15.
SO WE HAD BEEN IN THAT CLOSET
FOR ABOUT AN HOUR AND A HALF.
I OPENED THE DOOR AND I PEEKED
OUT 'CAUSE MY OFFICE HAS A LOT
OF WINDOWS.
AND LOOKED INTO THE COURTYARD
AND I JUST SAW WHAT LOOKED LIKE
MAYBE SWAT PEOPLE, BUT I DIDN'T
KNOW WHO THEY WERE.
I DIDN'T KNOW IF THERE WERE
OTHER SHOOTERS.
IT WASN'T UNTIL ABOUT 1:15 WHEN
SOMEBODY WAS JIGGLING THE DOOR
AND, BUT NOBODY CALLED OUT.
SO I DECIDED TO BE BRAVE ENOUGH
AND OPEN THAT DOOR INTO THE
OFFICE AND A LOT OF STATE POLICE
OFFICERS WERE THERE AT THAT
POINT.
THEY WERE VERY SURPRISED TO SEE
ME.
>> Steve: SHE WAS IN THERE FOR
FOUR HOURS.
SHE SAYS THAT FRIDAY STARTED
JUST LIKE EVERY OTHER DAY THERE
AT SANDY HOOK.
9:15, PLEDGE OF ALLEGIANCE.
9:20, DOORS LOCKED.
9:30, WE KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
THEY HAD BEEN PREPARING FOR
EMERGENCIES LIKE THAT EVERY
MONTH.
HERE ONCE AGAIN, SALLY COX, A
SCHOOL NURSE.
>> WE HAVE DIFFERENT KINDS OF
DRILLS.
IN ADDITION TO FIRE DRILLS AND
HIGH WIND DRILLS AND LOCKDOWN
DRILLS AND EVACUATION DRILLS.
SO WE'VE DONE IT.
WE'VE BEEN DOING IT EACH MONTH
IT'S SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
>> SO YOU HAD DONE THOSE KIND OF
THINGS FAIRLY RECENTLY?
>> YEP.
>> Brian: ONE STORY THAT IS
ABSOLUTELY STUNNING TO ME IS
VICTORIA SOTO, THE 27-YEAR-OLD
SINGLE TEACH WHO ARE PUT HER
KIDS IN THE CLOSET, TOLD THE
GUNMAN THEY'RE ALL DOWN AT THE
AUDITORIUM AND SIX KIDS PANICKED
AND RAN OUT.
SHE DOVE IN FRONT OF THEM.
THEY GOT KILLED.
THE REST IN THE CLOSET, THE
TRAUMA THEY MUST BE SEVERANCING
NOW IS BEYOND BELIEF.
IF A NAVY SEAL DID THIS, I'D BE
IN AWE.
BUT FOR A TEACH BETTER NO
EXPERIENCE TO HAVE THOSE
INSTINCTS IS ABSOLUTELY
INCREDIBLE.
ONE OF THE THINGS THAT PERHAPS
SAVED A NUMBER OF LIVES IS
DURING THE COMMOTION, SOMEBODY
IN THE OFFICE KEYED THE PUBLIC
ADDRESS SYSTEM AND PEOPLE COULD
HEAR THROUGHOUT THE BUILDING,
THEN COULD HEAR A SCREAM AND
COULD HEAR GUN SHOTS.
IT WAS ONLY ON FOR A COUPLE OF
SECONDS, BUT THAT WAS ENOUGH AND
THE TEACHERS STARTED LOCKING THE
DOORS FROM THE INSIDE.
HOW MANY CHILDREN'S LIVES WERE
SAVED BECAUSE SOMEBODY HAD THE
QUICK THINKING TO DO JUST THAT?
>> Gretchen: THIS WILL PROBABLY
CHANGE THE WAY IN WHICH SO MANY
SCHOOLS VIEW SECURITY AND WHAT'S
NEXT?
WHERE HAVE WE COME TO IN A
CULTURE WHERE WE HAVE TO RETHINK
ALL OF THIS ABOUT OUR KIDS BEING
SAFE AT SCHOOL?
>> Brian: COMING UP STRAIGHT
AHEAD, SUPPOSED TO BE THE MOST
DETAILED REPORT YET ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED IN BENGHAZI.
IT'S DUE OUT WITHIN HOURS.
WILL IT PROVIDE ANY ANSWERS?
THAT'S THE KEY.
>> Steve: AND HE SEARCHED FOR
HIS LOST DOG FOR FIVE YEARS.
AND THE MOMENT HE'S REUNITED IS
CAUGHT ON CAMERA.
WE'RE GOING TO SHOW IT TO YOU
anh
and creamy...
is it really 100 calories?
Let me put you on webcan...
...lean roasted chicken...
and a creamy broth
Mmm
I can still see you.
[ Male announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
A BODY AT REST
TENDS TO STAY AT REST...
WHILE A BODY IN MOTION
TENDS TO STAY IN MOTION.
STAYING ACTIVE CAN ACTUALLY
EASE ARTHRITIS SYMPTO.
BUT IF YOU HAVE ARTHRITIS,
STAYING ACTIVE
CAN BE DIFFICULT.
PRESCRIPTION CELEBREX
CAN HELP RELIEVE ARTHRITIS PAIN
SO YOUR BODY
CAN STAY IN MOTION.
BECAUSE JUST ONE
200MG CELEBREX A DAY
CAN PROVIDE 24 HOUR RELIEF
FOR MANY WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND INFLAMMATION.
PLUS, IN CLINICAL STUDIES,
CELEBREX IS PROVEN TO IMPROVE
DAILY PHYSICAL FUNCTION
SO MOVING IS EASIER.
CELEBREX CAN BE TAKEN WITH
OR WITHOUT FOOD.
AND IT'S NOT A NARCOTIC.
YOU AND YOUR DOCTOR
SHOULD BALANCE THE BENETS
WITH THEISKS.
ALL PRESCRIPTION NSAIDS,
LIKE CELEBREX, IBUPROFEN,
NAPROXEN, AND MELOXICAM
HAVE THE SAME
CARDIOVASCULAR WARNING.
THEY ALL MAY INCREASE
THE CHANCE
OF HEART ATTACK OR STROKE,
WHICH CAN LEAD TO DEATH.
THIS CHANCE INCREASES
IF YOU HAVE HEART DISEASE
RISK FACTORS
SUH AS HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE
OR WHEN NSAIDS ARE TAKEN
FOR LONG PERIODS.
NSAIDS, INCLUDING CELEBREX,
INCREASE THE CHANCE OF SERIOUS
SKIN OR ALLERGIC REACTIONS
OR STOMACH A INTESTINE
PROBLEMS,
SUCH AS BLEEDING AND CERS,
WHICH CAN OCCUR WITHOUT WARNING
AND MAY CAUSE DEATH.
PATIENTS ALSO TAKING ASPIRIN
AND THE ELDEY
ARE AT INCRSED RISK FOR
STOCH BLEEDING AND ULCERS.
DO NOT TAKE CELEBREX IF YOU'VE
HAD AN ASTHMA ATTACK, HIVES,
OR OTHER ALLERGIES TO ASPIRIN,
NSAIDS OR SULFONAMIDES.
GET HELP RIGHTWAY IF YOU HAVE
SWELNG OF THE FACE OR THROAT,
OR TROUBLE BREATHING.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
YOUR MEDICAL HISTORY
AND FIND AN ARTHRITIS TREATMENT
FOR YOU.
VISIT CELEBREX.COM AND ASK
YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT CELEBREX.
FOR A BODY IN MOTION.
they see more than themselves.
look in the mirror,
VISIT CELEBREX.COM AND ASK
YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT CELEBREX.
So we celebrate our year-end
with the "share the love" event.
Get a great deal on a new Subaru
and 250 dollars goes to your
choice of five charities.
By the end of this, our fifth
year,
our total can reach almost 25
million dollars.
It's a nice reflection on us
all.
Now through January 2nd.
Get 0% APR financing for 36
months on a 2013 Subaru Forester
and we'll donate 250 dollars to
your choice of 5 charities.
>> Gretchen: GOOD MORNING,
EVERYBODY.
THANK YOU FOR SHARING YOUR TIME
WITH US TODAY ON MONDAY, IT'S
DECEMBER 17, 2012.
I'M GRETCHEN CARLSON.
BRAND-NEW INFORMATION JUST
COMING IN NOW ABOUT ADAM LANZA
AND HIS MOTHER.
WHAT HAPPENED IN THE DAYS BEFORE
HE SNAPPED?
THE MOTHER'S CONFIDANTE IN HIS
FIRST TV INTERVIEW.
>> Steve: AT THIS POINT, WE MAY
NOT HAVE A MOTIVE IN THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING, BUT THERE IS ONE THING
WE DO KNOW, NEWTOWN KILLER, A
FAN OF VIDEO GAMES WERE VIOLENT.
ARE WE TRAINING KIDS TO KILL BY
HAVING THEM INSIDE GAMES LIKE
THIS ONE?
>> Brian: EVERY WEEK WE GIVE YOU
A LIST OF COMPANIES READY TO
HIRE AND HERE IS WHY.
ONE VIEWER JUST LANDED HER DREAM
JOB WITH OUR HELP.
CHERYL CASONE HERE LIVE.
"FOX & FRIENDS" STARTS RIGHT NOW
>> Steve: WELCOME TO THE
PROGRAM.
GRETCHEN AND I ARE WEARING A
LITTLE GREEN.
A NOTE WENT OUT ACROSS THE
COUNTRY ON FRIDAY, HEY, WEAR
BLUE TO SUPPORT THE SCHOOL.
AS IT TURNS OUT, SOMEBODY LOOKED
UP SANDY HOOK SCHOOL AND FOUND
OUT THAT THE COLORS WERE BLUE
AND YELLOW.
THAT TURNS OUT TO HAVE BEEN THE
SCHOOL COLORS OF THE HIGH
SCHOOL.
THE GRADE SCHOOL COLORS ARE
GREEN AND WHITE.
SO AS YOU PREPARE FOR THE DAY,
WEAR A LITTLE BLUE OR GREEN,
CLEARLY YOUR THOUGHTS WILL BE
WITH THE PEOPLE OF SANDY HOOK.
>> Brian: ALL RIGHT.
STRAIGHT UP, BRAND-NEW
INFORMATION COMING IN ABOUT ADAM
LANZA AND HIS MOM.
WHAT HAPPENED BEFORE HE WENT ON
THAT KILLING SPREE?
PETER DOOCY JUST SPOKE WITH A
FRIEND OF NANCY LANZA AND JOINS
US NOW FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
TO TRY TO GET INSIDE AND FIND
OUT FOR SURE WHAT THE MOTIVE
MIGHT HAVE BEEN.
PETER WHAT, DO YOU KNOW?
>> BRIAN, I KNOW THAT I SPOKE TO
A REGULAR AT ONE OF THE
RESTAURANTS THAT NANCY LANZA
LIKED TO GO TO, CALLED MY PLACE,
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
AND THIS MAN, RICH COLLINS, TOLD
ME THAT SINCE HE HAS A SON, A
TEENAGE SON WITH AUTISM AND
NANCY'S SON, ADAM, HAD
ASBURGERS, THE TWO OF THEM WOULD
BOND OVER THE DIFFICULTIES OF
RAISING THEIR CHILDREN AND WHAT
HE JUST TOLD ME IS VERY
REVEALING.
>> NANCY WOULD GET UPSET BECAUSE
HER SON REFUSED TO LET HER TOUCH
HIM.
SHE COULDN'T HUG HIM.
WHERE MY SON IS JUST THE
OPPOSITE.
SHE'D SEE MY SON HANGING ALL
OVER ME, BUT AUTISTIC KIDS, EACH
AND EVERY ONE OF THEM IS
DIFFERENT.
>> YOU SAID THAT THERE WERE
DIFFERENT THINGS THAT SHE TRIED
TO DO BECAUSE SHE HAD A HARD
TIME BONDING WITH HIM.
>> YES.
SHE WAS TRYING TO BOND, FIND
WAYS TO BOND WITH HIM.
SHE TOLD ME THE GUNS, SHE WOULD
TAKE THEM SHOOTING BECAUSE THAT
WAS A WAY THAT A SINGLE MOM
COULD RELATE TO HER SON AND SO
SHE WOULD TAKE HIM OUT SHOOTING.
>> RICH ALSO TOLD ME HE DOESN'T
THINK NANCY, AS A SINGLE MOM H
THE KIND OF SUPPORT SYSTEM THAT
SHE NEEDED TO DEAL WITH HER SON,
ADAM.
NOW, LAST NIGHT IT IS WORTH
POINTING OUT, PRESIDENT OBAMA
DID SPECIFICALLY MENTION MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS WHILE HE
WAS PROMISING TO STOP SENSELESS
SHOOTING SPREES IN THE FUTURE.
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS, I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT, MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS, TO PARENTS
AND EDUCATORS IN AN EFFORT AIMED
AT PREVENTING MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS.
>> EVEN THOUGH THE WEATHER HERE
FOR THE LAST 24 HOURS OR SO HAS
BEEN COLD AND WET, THERE HAVE
BEEN LOTS OF PEOPLE OUT PAYING
THEIR RESPECTS TO THE FALLEN AT
MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS AND AT
VIGILS.
WE DO EXPECT TO GET MORE
INFORMATION SOMETIME TODAY FROM
THE POLICE ABOUT THE LATEST IN
THEIR INVESTIGATION.
BACK TO YOU.
>> Steve: ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
>> Gretchen: AND AN EMOTIONALLY
TRYING DAY AHEAD IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THE FIRST OF THE FUNERALS ARE
BEING HELD.
ONE FOR THE YOUNGEST VICTIMS,
NOAH POSNER TURNED SIX LAST
MONTH.
THE OTHER FOR SIX-YEAR-OLD JACK
PINTO.
BECAUSE HE'S SUCH A HUGE GIANTS
FAN, HIS PARENTS MAY BURY HIM IN
HIS FAVORITE JERSEY.
THAT BRINGS US TO THE STORY OF
ONE LITTLE GIRL OUT OF THE
ENTIRE CLASS WHO HAPPENED TO
SURVIVE.
15 KIDS IN THE CLASS, THEY WERE
ALL SHOT DEAD.
BUT SHE DECIDED TO PLAY DEAD.
YOU HAVE TO ASK YOURSELF, HOW
DOES A SIX-YEAR-OLD KNOW HOW TO
DO THAT?
SHE HAD THE MENTAL CAPACITY -- I
DON'T KNOW.
HOPEFULLY THERE WAS SOME INNER
STRENGTH IN HER THAT I'D LIKE TO
BELIEVE THAT I DON'T KNOW WHAT
IT WAS, BUT SHE SURVIVED.
>> Brian: I WONDER IF THAT
MATCHES UP WITH THE STORY WE
HEARD INITIALLY OF A CHILD
WALKING OUT WITH BLOOD ON THEM,
BUT WAS OKAY.
THAT MUST HAVE BEEN BECAUSE SHE
WALKED OUT WITH BLOOD ON HER OF
THAT OF HER FRIENDS SAYING I'M
OKAY.
ALL MY FRIENDS ARE DEAD (QUITE A
STORY.
MEANWHILE, JOINING US NOW IS THE
HOST OF "HUCKABEE," A FELLOW
NAMED GOVERNOR MIKE HUCKABEE.
HE JOINSES FROM HIS HOME DOWN IN
FLORIDA.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
>> GOOD MORNING, STEVE, BRIAN,
GRETCHEN.
>> Steve: GREAT TO HAVE YOU.
ON FRIDAY MORNING AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, SCHOOL PRAYER
RETURNED TO THAT PUBLIBECAUSE OE
HEARING THIS MORNING, AS WE
HEARD OVER THE WEEKEND, WAS SO
MANY OF THE TEACHERS HUDDLED
THEIR CHILDREN IN CORNERS AND
CLOSETS AND THEY PRAYED
TOGETHER.
>> I THINK IT'S A COMMON HUMAN
REACTION WHEN ALL OF OUR HUMAN
ANSWERS HAVE FAILED, THAT'S WHEN
WE MAYBE FINALLY RECOGNIZE THAT
WE REALLY NEED GOD.
AND I'M NOT SUGGESTING BY ANY
STRETCH THAT IF WE HAD PRAYER IN
SCHOOLS REGULARLY AS WE ONCE DID
THAT THIS WOULDN'T HAVE
HAPPENED, 'CAUSE YOU CAN'T HAVE
THAT KIND OF DIRECT CAUSE AND
EFFECT.
BUT WE'VE CREATED AN ATMOSPHERE
IN THIS COUNTRY WHERE THE ONLY
TIME WE WANT TO INVOKE GOD'S
NAME IS AFTER THE TRAGEDY AND
I'M GRATEFUL, THE PRESIDENT
QUOTED SCRIPTURE.
HE TALKED VERSUS FROM THE NEW
TESTAMENT AND THAT'S GOOD.
WE NEED THAT COMFORT.
BUT WE NEED TO CREATE AN
ATMOSPHERE IN THIS COUNTRY WHERE
MORALITY IS NOT SOMETHING WE
DISCUSS ONLY WHEN WE HAVE NO
OTHER PLACE TO RUN, WHICH I'M
AFRAID SOMETIMES IS THE WAY IT
GOES.
WE CRITICIZE ANYBODY WHO INVOKES
GOD'S NAME, EXCEPT AFTER A
TRAGEDY LIKE THIS AND THEN IT
SEEMS TO BE OKAY.
>> Gretchen: EXACTLY.
WHEN I PUT MY CHILDREN TO BED AT
NIGHT, I SAY GOD IS ALWAYS WITH
YOU, WHEN YOU WAKE UP AND YOU'RE
LONELY, KNOW HE'S WITH YOU.
YESTERDAY AT OUR CHURCH,
GOVERNOR, IT WAS JUST SO MOVING.
THEY LIT A CANDLE FOR EVERY ONE
OF THE VICTIMS AND THEY HONORED
THEM AND IT WAS SO WONDERFUL TO
KNOW THAT IF YOU WERE A PERSON
OF FAITH, THAT YOU HAVE A LOT OF
QUESTIONS WHY, BUT YOU HAVE
SOMETHING TO HOLD ON TO.
>> I HEARD IT ONCE SAID,
GRETCHEN, AND I THINK IT'S AN
APPLICABLE STATEMENT THAT EVEN
IF YOU'RE A BELIEVER, YOU STILL
HIT BOTTOM, BUT AT LEAST YOU
FIND OUT IT IS SOLID AT THE
BOTTOM.
AND SO IT'S NOT THAT WE'RE
SPARED FROM GRIEF OR PAIN OR
SUFFERING, 'CAUSE WE'RE NOT.
BUT WE KNOW THAT THERE IS A
WORLD THAT GOES BEYOND THE EVIL
AND THE HORRORS OF THIS ONE AND
GIVES US SOME PERSPECTIVE TO
LIVE FOR.
IF WE DIDN'T HAVE THAT HOPE, IF
THERE WAS NOT -- AGAIN, I REFER
TO WHAT THE PRESIDENT SAID LAST
NIGHT.
HE SPOKE OF HEAVEN.
THOSE ARE WORDS OF HOPE.
IF WE DON'T BELIEVE THAT THERE
IS SUCH A PLACE, THAT THERE IS
SOMETHING BEYOND THIS PHYSICAL
LIFE WE LIVE, THEN THERE IS NO
HOPE.
AND I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT THAT
WE QUIT APOLOGIZING FOR HAVING A
SPIRITUAL CONVERSATION, THAT WE
SOMEHOW QUIT BEING ASHAMED THAT
WE BELIEVE IN GOD AND WE
RECOGNIZE, IT'S THE ONLY THING
THAT KEEPS US TOGETHER WHEN
THERE IS AN INEXPLICABLE TRAGEDY
LIKE THE ONE WE'VE SEEN WITH SO
MUCHOR AND PAIN.
>> Brian: GOVERNOR, AS I
MENTIONED WHEN YOU WERE ON THE
COUCH ON SATURDAY, IS THAT THE
TOWN GOT IT TOGETHER.
THEY SEEM LIKE A VERY SPIRITUAL
PLACE, THE IDEAL TOWN.
YOU SKETCHED THIS OUT IN A
CHILDREN'S BOOK AND SAY THIS IS
WHERE YOU WANT TO GROW UP.
THEIR REACTION IN THE TIMES IN
WHICH THE SHOOTING WAS TAKEN
PLACE, HEROIC.
THEIR ACTIONS AFTERWARDS,
TREMENDOUS EMPATHY AND SYMPATHY
FROM AROUND THE WORLD.
THE GOD THAT NEEDED GOD WAS THE
SHOOTER.
AND THE ASSAILANT IS THE
PROBLEM.
NOT THE PEOPLE IN THE TOWN.
>> WHEN WE CREATE AN ATMOSPHERE,
WHEN WE TELL PEOPLE GOD REALLY
ISN'T A PART OF OUR CREATION,
THAT WE'RE JUST BIOLOGICAL
ACCIDENTS AND THEN WE RAISE A
WHOLE GENERATION TO BELIEVE THAT
HE'S IRRELEVANT, THAT IT'S FOR
PEOPLE WHO DON'T HAVE THE
INTELLECTUAL CAPACITY TO THINK
BIGGER THAN THAT, THAT IT'S FOR
SIMPLETONS TO BELIEVE IN GOD,
WHAT SHOULD WE EXPECT?
THIS IS THE NET RESULT.
WE REAP WHAT WE SOW WHEN WE ONLY
INVOKE GOD AFTER THE CRISIS, BUT
WE DON'T CREATE THE ATMOSPHERE
IN WHICH WE SAY, WE ARE
ACCOUNTABLE, THAT WE ARE SPECIAL
BECAUSE WE'RE CREATED WITH A
PURPOSE.
GIVE A PERSON A PURPOSE, A SENSE
OF REASON FOR EXISTENCE THAT HE
OR SHE IS THE CREATION OF AN
ALMIGHTY, ALL KNOWING GOD AND
YOU GIVE THAT PERSON A BASIS FOR
LIVING THAT A PERSON DOES NOT
HAVE IF YOU HONESTLY THINK THAT
YOU'RE NOTHING MORE THAN A BLOB
OF PROCEED PROTO PLATFORM WITH
NOTHING BEYOND THIS LIFE.
>> Steve: OUR GUN LAWS AND
THINGS LIKE THAT, THERE WILL BE
A BROADER DISCUSSION LOOKING AT
HOW WE HAVE GLORIFIED VIOLENCE
IN OUR CULTURE, WHETHER IT'S THE
MOVIES OR THE VIDEO GAMES OR
JUST THE COARSENING OF THE
CULTURE ITSELF.
>> STEVE, THAT'S AN IMPORTANT
DISCUSSION FOR US TO HAVE.
WHEN WE SEPARATE VIOLENCE FROM
SOME PURPOSE, PEOPLE WILL SAY,
BUT THE BIBLE HAS VIOLENCE.
IT DOES.
BUT THAT VIOLENCE WAS ALWAYS
COUCHED IN THE TERMS OF MORAL
GOODNESS OR MORAL EVIL.
IT WAS NEVER NEUTRAL.
AND THAT'S WHERE WE END UP WITH
WHEN VIOLENCE BECOMES A PART OF
SOME NEUTRAL EXPRESSION AND
THAT'S THE TROUBLE WITH SOME OF
THE GAMES.
NOT THAT EVERY KID WHO PLAYS A
VIDEO GAME IS A POTENTIAL MASS
MURDERER 'CAUSE THAT'S NONSENSE.
BUT A CHILD WHO ALREADY HAS A
PROPENSITY TOWARDS PSYCHOLOGICAL
DISCONNECTS AND THEN YOU LOCK
THAT KID IN HIS ROOM WITH A
COMPUTER SCREEN AND A SMART
PHONE, WITH VIDEO GAMES AND HE
DOESN'T HAVE HUMAN CONNECTION,
HIS ONLY CONNECTION TO THE WORLD
IS ELECTRONIC AND A LOT OF THAT
IS MOLDED BY THESE INCREDIBLY
VIOLENT IMAGES, AND I THINK WE
END UP SEEING THAT YOU CAN NOT
OPERATE A CIVIL SOCIETY IN A
MORAL VACUUM.
THERE HAS TO BE SOME SENSE IN
WHICH MORALITY EXISTS AND THEN
THE QUESTION COMES, WHERE DOES
MORALITY COME FROM?
IT DOESN'T JUST ESTABLISH
ITSELF.
IF THERE IS NOT AN OBJECTIVE
STANDARD IN OUR CASE, I THINK
WE'D SAY THERE IS A GOD WHO
GIVES US THE STANDARD, THEN
EVERYBODY GETS TO MAKE UP HIS
OWN RULES AND THAT'S WHEN A
CULTURE AND A CIVILIZATION
COMPLETELY FALLS APART.
>> Steve: GREAT CONVERSATION.
GOVERNOR HUCKABEE, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH, ESPECIALLY COMING ON
THIS DAY WHEN THE FIRST OF THE
TWO VICTIMS ARE GOING TO BE
BURIED IN CONNECTICUT.
THANK YOU.
>> YOU BET.
>> Gretchen: IMPORTANT WORDS
FROM GOVERNOR HUCKABEE.
FOX NEWS ALERT NOW.
WE'VE JUST LEARNED THE MAN
SUSPECTED OF SHOOTING AND
KILLING TWO TOPEKA, KANSAS
POLICE OFFICERS HAVE BEEN CAUGHT
AND NOW HOSPITALIZED.
ACCORDING TO OUR AFFILIATES IN
KANSAS, COPS USED TEAR GAS TO
GET 22-YEAR-OLD DAVID TUSCARINO
OUT OF HIS HOME.
HE OPENED FIRED ON THE OFFICERS
AS THEY WERE RESPONDING TO A
CALL.
HIS CONDITION IS NOT CLEAR AT
THIS TIME.
THE OFFICERS THAT HE KILLED
ALLEGEDLY, 50-YEAR-OLD CORPORAL
DAVID GOGIAN, RECENTLY RETIRED
FROM THE MILITARY.
HIS SON IS ALSO A TOPEKA POLICE
OFFICER.
ALSO 29-YEAR-OLD JEFF ATTARLY
KILLED.
HE JUST JOINED THE FORCE LAST
YEAR.
>>> AMERICAN INJURED OVERNIGHT
IN A BOMB BLAST IN KABUL,
AFGHANISTAN.
THIS IS BRAND-NEW VIDEO OF THE
AFTERMATH OF THAT CAR BOMBING.
OUTSIDE A COMPOUND, HOUSING A
U.S. MILITARY CONTRACTOR.
TWO AFGHAN WORKERS DIED IN THE
ATTACK.
THE TALIBAN HAS CLAIMED
RESPONSIBILITY.
>>> MOST DETAILED REPORT ON THE
BENGHAZI, LIBYA TERRORIST ATTACK
RELEASED TODAY.
THE INDEPENDENT ADVISORY REVIEW
BOARD WILL DELIVER ITS
ASSESSMENT.
CONGRESS WILL SEE IT.
THE STATE DEPARTMENT WILL THEN
MAKE RECOMMENDATIONS ON
IMPROVING SECURITY.
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON ORDERED THIS REVIEW, BUT
SHE WILL NOT TESTIFY NOW ABOUT
BENGHAZI, AT LEAST NOT THIS
THURSDAY AFTER FAINTING AND
SUFFERING A CONCUSSION.
>>> THE LATEST MOON MISSION
COMING TO A CRASHING END.
NASA'S TWIN SPACE PROBE NAMED E
EBB AND FLOW WILL CRASH INTO THE
MOON'S SURFACE.
THEY'VE BEEN ORGET BITTING THE
MOON FOR A YEAR ACTION CREATING
A DETAILED MAP.
THE MISSION IS COMPLETE.
>>> THOSE ARE YOUR HEADLINES.
>> Steve: KABOOM.
ALL RIGHT.
ON THIS MONDAY, EVERY WEEK WE
BRING YOU COMPANIES THAT ARE
HIRING AND HERE IS WHY.
ONE VIEWER LANDED HER DREAM JOB
WITH THE HELP OF CHERYL CASONE
AND FOX AND FRIENDS AND SHE'S
HERE WITH HER STORY.
>> Brian: ONE THING WE DO KNOW
ABOUT THE NEWTOWN KILLER, HE WAS
A FAN OF VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES AND
ARE WE TRAINING OUR KIDS TO
KILL?
THE VIDEO GAMES HAVE ANYTHING TO
DO WITH REALITY?
PETER JOHNSON, JR. EXPLORES.
BEGIN.
TOMATO,
OBVIOUSLY.
HAHA. THERE'S MORE
THAN THAT THOUGH,
THERE'S A KICK TO IT.
WAHLALALALALLALA!
SMOOTH, BUT CRISP.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE DRINKING
A FOOD THAT'S A DRINK,
OR A DRINK THAT'S A FOOD,
WOOOOOH!
[ Male Announcer ] TASTE IT
AND DESCRIBE THE INDESCRIBABLE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
[ coughs ]
[ baby crying ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
ROBITUSSIN® LIQUID FORMULA
SOOTHES YOUR THROAT ON CONTACT
AND THE ACTIVE INGREDIENT
RELIEVES YOUR COUGH.
ROBITUSSIN®. DON'T SUFFER
THE COUGHEQUENCES™.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a
Droid Incredible 4G LTE
by HTC for $49.99.
>> Steve: MANY QUESTIONS
FOLLOWING FRIDAY'S DEVASTATING
TRAGEDY, NAMELY WHY DID IT
HAPPEN?
HOLLYWOOD AND VIDEO GAME
INDUSTRY MAKE BILLIONS OF
DOLLARS GLORIFYING DEATH AND
MASS MURDER.
THE HIGHEST RATED FILMS FOR 2012
WERE RATED R FOR VIOLENCE.
ADAM LANZA WAS A BIG FAN FOR
MANY YEARS OF VIOLENT VIDEO
GAMES.
FOX NEWS LEGAL ANALYST PETER
JOHNSON, JR. JOINS US NOW.
WE DON'T KNOW IF THERE WAS
ACTION, BUT WE KNOW HE WAS A FAN
OF THEM.
>> WE KNOW THAT AND WE DO KNOW
THE CULTURE OF MAYHEM AND MASS
DEATH IS BEING PEDDLED BY
HOLLYWOOD AND THERE IS A CERTAIN
AMOUNT OF HYPOCRISY THAT GOES
INTO IT BECAUSE UNFORTUNATELY,
VERY OFTEN THESE ARE THE SAME
PEOPLE THAT SAY, WELL, THE
REASON FOR VIOLENCE IN THIS
COUNTRY IS THE ABILITY TO MEET
THE NEEDS OF THE CONSTITUTION
AND ALLOW PEOPLE TO OWN GUNS.
>> Steve: RIGHT.
>> THERE IS AN ISSUE ON GUN
CONTROL THAT NEEDS TO BE
ENFORCED.
WE NEED LAWS THAT PROTECT PEOPLE
AGAINST UNNECESSARY VIOLENCE.
WE NEED TO ALLOW PEOPLE TO USE
HAND GUNS OR TO USE RIFLES FOR
SPORT AND SELF-DEFENSE.
NOT FOR OTHER USES.
BUT AT THE SAME TIME, WE KNOW
THAT WHEN WE SPENT $17 BILLION A
YEAR ON VIDEO GAMES, WE KNOW
THAT THERE IS AN OHIO STATE
STUDY THAT SHOWS THAT AGGRESSION
AND VIDEO GAME WATCHING GO
TOGETHER.
IF YOU WATCH THEM FOR A LONG
TIME, YOU'LL BE MORE AGGRESSIVE.
WE KNOW THAT IT'S A PROBLEM IN
THIS COUNTRY AND WE HEARD THE
LIEUTENANT COLONEL TALK ABOUT
THIS MORNING ALL THESE NC-17
GAMES WHERE TIME AFTER TIME,
PERSON AFTER PERSON, BUILDING
AFTER BUILDING ARE BLOWN UP,
SHOT, EXPLODED AND THE ONLY
VALUE IS HOW MANY PEOPLE YOU CAN
KILL.
SO TALK ABOUT DESENSITIZATION.
WE NEED TO BE SENSITIVE TO OUR
CHILDREN.
WE NEED TO BE SENSITIVE TO
REFORMING LAWS IN THIS COUNTRY.
YES, IN TERMS OF MAKING SURE
THAT THERE ARE CHECKS AT GUN
SHOWS, BUT AT THE SAME TIME, WE
NEED TO UNDERSTAND THAT THE
MEDIUM IS THE MESSAGE AND THE
MEDIA'S MESSAGE IS DEATH AND
VIOLENCE AND I WAS IN NEWTOWN
AND YOUR GREAT JOURNALIST SON
WAS IN NEWTOWN AND YOU COVERED
IT ALL WEEKEND AND DEVASTATION
AND THE PAIN AND THE TRAGEDY IS
UNBELIEVABLE.
>> Steve: IT IS INDEED.
>> INCONSOLABLE.
SO IF WE DON'T LOOK AT WHAT
SENATOR LIEBERMAN TALKED ABOUT
IN TERMS OF THIS CULTURE OF MASS
VIOLENCE AND DEATH THROUGH
MEDIA, THEN WE WILL REAP THE
WHIRLWIND.
THIS WILL HAPPEN AGAIN AND AGAIN
AND AGAIN AS IT'S HAPPENED IN
THIS COUNTRY AND AROUND THE
WORLD.
>> Steve: AND THERE HAS BEEN THE
CONNECTION WITHED VIDEO GAMES.
I HEARD A STORY THIS MORNING
THAT APPARENTLY WHEN THE POLICE
WENT TO THE LANZA HOUSE, THE
MOTHER'S HOUSE, THE COMPUTERS
HAD PRETTY MUCH BEEN DESTROYED.
ADAM LANZA, BEFORE HE MURDERED
HER, DESTROYED THE COMPUTERS.
SO I'M SURE -- ALTHOUGH THEY SAY
THEY CAN GET DATA FROM THE HARD
DRIVE.
YOU TOUCHED ON DESENSITIZEATION.
LOOK AT THIS.
YOU PLAY A VIOLENT GAME FOR
THREE CONSECUTIVE DAYS AND
ALTERS YOUR BEHAVIOR.
EACH DAY AFTER PLAYERS SHOWED
INCREASE OF HOSTILITY AND
AGGRESSION.
PEOPLE WHO PLAYED NONVIOLENT
GAMES EXPERIENCED NO CHANGE.
AS A FIVE-YEAR-OLD, IF YOU START
PLAYING SONIC TO HEDGE HOG.
BUT THEN WHEN YOU'RE 15 AND --
>> IT'S A FRIGHTENING STUDY.
WE KNOW IT.
IT'S A MATTER OF COMMON SENSE.
IT'S ALSO A MATTER OF COMMON
SENSE AND WE KNOW THAT THE
HOLLYWOOD INDUSTRY IS CLINGING,
CLINGING TO GUNS ECONOMICALLY.
THEY ARE GLAMORIZING GUNS IN
THIS COUNTRY!
THEY ARE THE SCOURGE IN TERMS OF
THESE GUNS.
GUNS CAN KILL IF PEOPLE HAVE
EVIL INTENTIONS.
BUT DON'T TELL OUR CHILDREN THAT
IT'S ACCEPTABLE TO MOW DOWN
PEOPLE IN MALLS, IN CHURCHES, IN
SCHOOLS, ON THE STREET.
THEY DON'T KNOW BETTER.
THEY KNOW WHAT WE'RE TAUGHT AND
WE'RE TEACHING THEM WRONG.
>> Steve: THERE IS PARENTAL
RESPONSIBILITY.
IF YOU LET YOUR KID PLAY -- YOUR
TEN-YEAR-OLD PLAY A GAME
INTENDED FOR ADULTS, THEY'RE
GOING TO WIND UP BEING INSIDE
THAT ADULT'S VIDEO GAME WORLD.
>> WE HAVE ALL KINDS OF
CONTROLS.
AND HOLLYWOOD SHOULD START TO
POLICE ITSELF 'CAUSE DEATH
SHOULD NOT BE THE BY-PRODUCT OF
OUR ENTERTAINMENT.
>> Steve: AMEN.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Steve: 20 MINUTES AFTER THE
TOP OF THE HOUR.
SHE MADE IT OUT ALIVE, BUT JUST
BARELY.
>> YOU KNOW, THERE WAS A
HORRIBLE FEELING, YOU KNOW, JUST
LIKE A NIGHTMARE THAT I COULDN'T
BELIEVE THAT, YOU KNOW -- THAT
IT'S A BAD DREAM.
>> Steve: WHAT HAPPENED ON
FRIDAY IN THAT SCHOOL?
THE SCHOOL NURSE TELLS HER STORY
IN HER OWN WORDS.
AND A NEW WAVE OF VIOLENCE
HITTING BENGHAZI.
OVERNIGHT, BREAKING DETAILS
STRAIGHT AHEAD
You know how painful heartburn
can be.
For fast, long lasting relief,
use doctor recommended
Gaviscon®.
Only Gaviscon® forms a
protective barrier that helps
block stomach acid from
splashing up-
relieving the pain quickly.
Try fast, long lasting
Gaviscon®.
WITHOUT FRESHLY-MADE PASTA.
YOU COULD ALSO CUT CORNERS
BY MAKING IT WITHOUT
100% REAL CHEDDAR CHEESE.
BUT THEN...IT WOULDN'T BE
STOUFFER'S MAC & CHEESE.
JUST ONE OF OVER 70
SATISFYING RECIPES FOR ONE
FROM STOUFFER'S.
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAN
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
>> Brian: QUICK HEADLINES NOW.
OVERNIGHT, TWO POLICE STATIONS
IN BENGHAZI, LIBYA, TARGETED IN
SIMULTANEOUS ATTACKS.
SOURCES SAY A BOMB WAS THROWN
INTO A PARKED CAR AT ONE
STATION.
AT THE SAME TIME A BLAST WENT
OFF AT ANOTHER POLICE STATION.
NO ONE HURT IN EITHER ATTACK.
AND CAROLINA PANTHERS LINEBACKER
HAPPY.
HE'S GETTING HIGH FIVES FROM THE
FANS AFTER A BIG WIN.
WHEN THE GUARDRAIL GAVE WAY,
SENDING SOME FANS SPILLING ONTO
THE FIELD.
FRONT ROW FANS WERE A FOOT OR
TWO ABOVE FIELD LEVEL.
NO WORD IF ANYONE WAS HURT.
PANTHERS HAD JUST BEATEN THE SAN
DIEGO CHARGERS 31-7.
GRETCH?
>> Gretchen: THANK YOU, BRIAN.
AS WE ALL KNOW, BEING
UNEMPLOYED, ESPECIALLY TOUGH
DURING THE HOLIDAY SEASON.
BUT EVEN IN A BAD ECONOMY, THERE
ARE COMPANIES LOOKING FOR NEW
EMPLOYEES AND EACH WEEK WE GIVE
YOU HOPE BECAUSE WE GIVE YOU A
LIST OF THEM.
TODAY WE NEED A HAPPY STORY,
DON'T WE?
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE A SUCCESS
STORY FOR YOU RIGHT NOW.
SLAYS LOCKHART IS A "FOX &
FRIENDS" VIEWER AND HIRED AS
CARE GIVER BY RIGHT AT HOME, A
JOB SHE HEARD ABOUT ON OUR
WEEKLY ON THE JOB HUNT SEGMENT.
SHE'S JOINED BY THE COMPANY'S
PRESIDENT AND COO.
GOOD TO HAVE YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Gretchen: YOU HAD HEARD ON
"FOX & FRIENDS" THAT ONCE A WEEK
WE DID THESE SEGMENTS WHERE WE
TALKED ABOUT THE FIVE TOP
COMPANIES HIRING.
AND YOU SAW ONE AND THOUGHT, I
CAN DO THAT.
>> RIGHT.
I ACTUALLY -- MY JOB SEARCH
STARTED WHEN I WAS LOOKING FOR A
JOB AND I TRIED TO APPLY FOR
THREE DIFFERENT POSITION IN THE
CARE GIVING FIELD.
NOTHING PANNED OUT.
I HAPPENED TO BE WATCHING "FOX &
FRIENDS" ON TUESDAY AND THEY HAD
A SEGMENT ON FOR A JOB HUNT.
I SEEN YOU ADVERTISE THE SERVICE
AND I CALLED MY LOCAL FRANCHISE
AND THEY WERE HIRING AND I
APPLIED ON-LINE AND BEFORE I
KNEW IT, THEY WERE CALLING ME
FOR AN INTERVIEW AND ORIENTATION
AND I HAVE BEEN WORKING FOR THEM
FOR TWO MONTHS NOW.
>> Gretchen: BRIAN, YOU MUST BE
SO PLEASED TO BE PART OF A GOOD
NEWS STORY TODAY.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> Gretchen: HERE YOU ARE IN
CHARGE OF A COMPANY THAT HELPS
PEOPLE COME INTO HOMES AND
PROVIDE CARE.
TELL US MORE ABOUT YOUR COMPANY.
>> YEAH.
RIGHT AT HOME HAS BEEN A IN-HOME
CARE PROVIDER FOR 17 YEARS, WE
STARTED IN 1995.
OUR FOUNDER STARTED IN OMAHA,
NEBRASKA WITH A SINGLE HOME CARE
COMPANY AND HAD A GREAT BUSINESS
MODEL AND A GREAT VISION AND
WANTED TO EXPAND SERVICES ACROSS
THE COUNTRY AND BRING THAT
CONCEPT ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
SO WE STARTED FRANCHISING IN
2000 AND TODAY WE HAVE 278
LOCATIONS IN 42 STATES AND FIVE
ADDITIONAL COUNTRIES OUTSIDE OF
THE U.S.
>> Gretchen: WOW.
SO LISA, I UNDERSTAND THAT IT
WAS YOUR VIBRANT PERSONALITY
THAT MADE IT AN AUTOMATIC YES
WHEN YOUR JOB APPLICATION CAME
IN.
WHAT DO YOU DO?
I KNOW WORKS OUT REALLY WELL
WITH YOUR SCHEDULE WITH YOUR
CHILDREN.
>> RIGHT.
AS FAR AS --
>> Gretchen: YOU GO IN AND TAKE
CARE OF PEOPLE, BUT YOU GET O
DROP YOUR KIDS OFF AT SCHOOL?
>> RIGHT.
I HAVE MY SCHEDULE WORK WITH MY
KIDS 'CAUSE I CAN DROP THEM OFF
AND THEN I'M WORKING AND WHEN I
GET HIM, WHEN I GET DONE AT
WORK, THEN I GO HOME AND TAKE
CARE OF MY CHILDREN.
>> Gretchen: WHAT DOES IT MEAN
TO YOU AFTER TWO WEEKS LOOKING
FOR A JOB TO HAVE EMPLOYMENT?
>> IT MEANS A LOT.
I ENJOY -- MY PASSION IS WITH
THE SENIOR CITIZENS.
YOU HAVE TO HAVE A HEART TO TAKE
CARE OF THE ELDERLY, AT THEIR
FRAGILE STATE, YOU KNOW, THAT
THEY'RE IN AT THE END.
>> Gretchen: HATS OFF TO BOTH OF
YOU.
I'M SO HAPPY YOU FOUND A JOB.
AND BRIAN, FOR YOU FOR LETTING
PEOPLE KNOW THAT JOBS ARE OUT
THERE AT YOUR COMPANY.
IT'S CALLED RIGHT AT HOME.
THANKS SO MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Gretchen: TOMORROW WE'LL HAVE
CHERYL CASONE WHO STARTED THESE
SEGMENTS FOR US.
SHE'S FROM THE "FOX BUSINESS"
NETWORK.
TOMORROW AT 7:50 A.M. EASTERN
TIME, SHE'S GOING TO HAVE FIVE
MORE COMPANIES WHO ARE HIRING
RIGHT NOW.
SO BREAK OUT YOUR PENS AND
PAPER.
GET READY FOR THAT.
COMING UP, SHE MADE IT OUT
ALIVE, JUST BARELY.
>> YOU KNOW, THERE WAS A
HORRIBLE FEELING, YOU KNOW, AND
JUST LIKE A NIGHTMARE THAT
COULDN'T BELIEVE THAT, YOU KNOW,
THINK IT'S A BAD DREAM.
>> Gretchen: THAT IS THE SCHOOL
NURSE AND SHE TELLS HER STORY IN
HER OWN WORDS.
THEN THE GOVERNMENT PUT ASIDE
BILLIONS TO HELP HURRICANE SANDY
VICTIMS.
SO WHY IS SOME OF THAT MONEY NOW
GOING ALL THE WAY TO ALASKA?
WE'LL TRY TO SORT THAT OUT FOR
YOU.
WHEN YOU DON'T USE NEW PAM,
THIS IS WHAT YOU GET.
RESIDUE.
[ Female Announcer ]
BARGAIN BRAND COOKING SPRAY
LEAVES ANNOYING RESIDUE.
THAT'S WHY THERE'S NEW PAM.
YOU HAVE A PLAN?
FIRST WE'RE GONNA
CHECK OUR BAGS FOR FREE,
THANKS
TO OUR EXPLORER CARD.
THEN, THE UNITED CLUB.
MY MOTR
WAS SO WRONG ABOUT YOU.
NEXT,
WE GET PRIORY BOARDING
ON OUR FLIGHT
I BOOKED WITH MILES.
ALL BECAUSE OF THE CARD.
AND ME.
OKAY, WHAT'S THE PLAN?
PLAN?
MM-HMM.
WE'RE ON VACATION.
THERE IS NO PLAN.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ] THE UNITED
MILEAGEPLUS EXPLORER CARD.
THE MILEAGE CARD
WITH SPECI PERKS ON UNITED.
GET IT AND YOU'RE IN.
>> Gretchen: TALK ABOUT THE
COMFORT OF COMPANIONS, A
TRUSTFUL GOLDEN RETRIEVER
ARRIVING IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
IT HELP THE SHOOTING SURVIVORS.
THESE DOGS SENT BY THE LUTHERAN
CHURCH NEAR CHICAGO, ILLINOIS,
THE THERAPY DOGS HAVE TRAVELED
TO SEE SUPER STORM SANDY VICTIMS
RECENTLY AND EVEN THOSE AFFECTED
BY THE TORNADO IN JOPLIN, MO M.
ABOUT TEN DOGS ARE IN NEWTOWN
RIGHT NOW.
FANTASTIC IDEA.
>> Brian: WE'RE WAITING A NEWS
CONFERENCE FROM POLICE IN
NEWTOWN ON THE DETAILS AND
MOTIVE BEHIND THE SHOOTING AND
AS WELL AS THE INVESTIGATION.
LIEUTENANT VANCE EXPECTED TO
SPEAK IN LESS THAN 30 MINUTES.
THIS IS THE GRIEVING COMMUNITY
PREPARING FOR THE FIRST
FUNERALS, THERE IS MORE THAN
ONE.
LAST NIGHT PRESIDENT OBAMA SPOKE
AT THE MEMORIAL FOR THE VICTIMS,
KELLY WRIGHT LIVE AT THE WHITE
HOUSE WITH MORE.
HEY, KELLY.
>> GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
HOPE YOU'RE DOING WELL.
THE NATION CONTINUES TO WEEP
WITH THOSE FAMILIES WHO HAVE
BEEN PAINFULLY SADDENED BY THE
TRAGIC INCIDENT OF THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
PRESIDENT OBAMA VISITED WITH
FAMILIES WHOSE LIVES HAVE BEEN
SHATTERED BY THIS SENSELESS ACT
OF VIOLENCE.
HE REACHED OUT TO EACH FAMILY TO
CONSOLE THEM IN THEIR TIME OF
GRIEF, TAKING PICTURES WITH THE
FAMILY MEMBERS AS WELL AND THEN
IN AN EMOTIONAL ADDRESS TO THE
COMMUNITY, HE SOUGHT TO DELIVER
HOPE AND COMFORT THROUGH
SCRIPTURE AND PRAYER.
>> GOD HAS CALLED THEM ALL HOME.
FOR THOSE OF US WHO REMAIN, LET
US FIND THE STRENGTH TO CARRY ON
AND MAKE OUR COUNTRY WORTHY OF
THEIR MEMORY.
>> AND PART OF DOING IT, THE
PRESIDENT PRAISED THE PEOPLE ON
HOW THEY INSPIRED IN PRAYING
TOGETHER.
>> IN THE FACE OF INDESCRIBABLE
VIOLENCE, IN THE FACE OF
UNCONCLUSIONABLE EVIL, YOU'VE
LOOKED OUT FOR EACH OTHER.
YOU'VE CARED FOR ONE ANOTHER.
YOU'VE LOVED ONE ANOTHER.
>> THE MASS SHOOTING, WHICH TOOK
THE LIVES OF 26 CHILDREN AND
ADULTS AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL ON FRIDAY SHOCKED THE
WORLD.
THE PRESIDENT SAID ACTS LIKE
THIS SHOULD NOT BE ACCEPTED AS
ROUTINE.
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS, I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT TO MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS TO PARENTS
AND EDUCATORS IN AN EFFORT AIMED
AT PREVENTING MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS.
>> THE PRESIDENT TOLD
CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR MALLOY
YESTERDAY THAT THIS WAS THE MOST
DIFFICULT DAY OF HIS PRESIDENCY.
OBVIOUSLY IN THE DAYS AND WEEKS
TO COME, IT WILL BE A DIFFICULT
TASK FOR THE PRESIDENT, AS WELL
AS MEMBERS OF CONGRESS ON BOTH
SIDES OF THE AISLE TO DETERMINE
WHAT SHOULD BE DONE TO PREVENT
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS FROM EVER
HAPPENING AGAIN.
BACK TO YOU.
>> Gretchen: I WANT TO SAY YOU
WERE ON "FOX & FRIENDS"
YESTERDAY AND YOU DID A REALLY,
REALLY GREAT JOB IN TRYING TO
TALK ABOUT A TERRIBLE SITUATION.
HATS OFF TO YOU.
>> I APPRECIATE THAT.
THANK YOU.
>> Steve: ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT NANCY
LANZA WHO WAS MURDERED IN HER
BED BY HER SON, ADAM.
PETER DOOCY JUST HAD AN
EXCLUSIVE, FIRST TV INTERVIEW
WITH A CONFIDANTE OF THAT WOMAN
RIGHT THERE, NANCY LANZA.
SHE WOULD GET UPSET THAT HER SON
WOULDN'T LET HER HUG HIM.
HE HAD AUTISM-RELATED ASBURGERS.
ALSO SHE WAS TRYING TO HELP HIM
BUILD A LIFE FOR HIMSELF, 20
YEARS OLD.
THEY WERE THINKING ABOUT HIM
MOVING TO A NEW TOWN FOR
COLLEGE.
MAYBE ENGINEERING SCHOOL.
THEY HAD ALREADY VISITED SCHOOLS
IN THE CAROLINAS AND IN SEATTLE
AND WHAT'S INTERESTING IS SHE
HAD APPARENTLY TOLD HER
CONFIDANTE THAT I WILL MOVE WITH
HIM.
BUT IT SOUNDS LIKE SHE WAS THE
ONE PUSHING HIM TO MOVE ON WITH
HIS LIFE.
HE WAS ALREADY 20 YEARS OLD.
THE BIG QUESTION IS, WHAT IF HE
DIDN'T ACTUALLY WANT TO GO?
COULD THAT POSSIBLY HAVE
IMPACTED HIM.
>> Brian: THE DAILY MAIL IN
BRITAIN SAID SHE HAD TOLD FAMILY
MEMBERS HAD TOLD THEM THAT --
SHE THOUGHT THE END OF THE WORLD
WAS COMING AND STOCKPILING GUN
FORCE THAT TIME AND A LOT OF
FOOD FOR THAT TIME.
AND SHE HAD SOMEBODY THAT LOVED
HUNTING TO THE POINT, GOING TO
THE DAILY -- ACCORDING TO THE
DAILY NEWS, SHE HUNTED WITH A
FALCON WHAT THANK WOULD SCARE
THE BIRDS INTO THE OPEN WHERE
SHE COULD SHOOT THEM.
SO SHE LOVED SHOOTING AND SHE
ACTUALLY INTRODUCED SHOOTING TO
HER SON.
>> Gretchen: SO MANY ISSUES HERE
THAT WILL NO DOUBT BE DISCUSSED
FOR WEEKS AND MONTHS AND MAYBE
YEARS TO COME.
MENTAL ILLNESS, TO GUN, TO
AUTISM, ET CETERA.
LET'S LOOK AT ONE OF THE PEOPLE
WHO KNEW OR TRIED TO GET TO KNOW
ADAM LANZA, HERE IS ONE OF HIS
CLASSMATES.
>> HE JUST WOULD GET VERY
NERVOUS AND HIS FACE WOULD TURN
BRIGHT RED AND HE WOULD GET VERY
FIDGETY.
YOU COULD JUST TELL THAT IT
WASN'T THAT HE DIDN'T KNOW THE
ANSWER.
IT'S JUST THAT IT WAS VERY
DIFFICULT FOR HIM TO SAY WHAT HE
WANTED TO SAY.
HE MUST HAVE REALLY FELT
UNCOMFORTABLE IN ANY KIND OF
SOCIAL SITUATION BECAUSE HE
NEVER REALLY PUT HIMSELF OUT
THERE AND I JUST DON'T REALLY
REMEMBER HIM EVER STEPPING
FORWARD OR REALLY SAYING
ANYTHING.
HE WANTED TO BE LEFT ALONE AND
WE LEFT HIM ALONE.
>> Brian: I SAW ONE OF THESE
ARTICLES THAT QUOTED THE NOTED
CHILD PSYCHIATRIST, AND HE SAYS
HAVING ASBURGERS,  WHICH HE IS
RUMORED TO HAVE IT, BY ITSELF
DOES NOT MAKE YOU LIKE THREE
KILL.
BUT HAVING IT, BEING SOCIALLY
AWKWARD, FEELING TRAPPED,
FEELING EDUCATIONALLY
OVERWHELMED, FEELING DESPAIR
WITHOUT ANY TOOLS TO GET YOU OUT
OF THAT BOX CAN LEAD A HUMAN
BEING TO DO DESPERATE THINGS.
>> Steve: AFTER EVENTS LIKE
THIS, PEOPLE ARE ALWAYS GOING,
HOW DID HE SLIP THROUGH THE
CRACKS?
APPARENTLY HE DIDN'T.
THE SCHOOL SYSTEM IDENTIFIED HIM
WHEN HE WAS IN MIDDLE SCHOOL
THAT THIS WAS SOMEBODY THEY
SHOULD WATCH.
WHEN HE WAS IN HIGH SCHOOL, HE
HAD A PERMANENT PSYCHOLOGIST,
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST ASSIGNED TO
HIM.
IT WASN'T THAT THEY WERE WORRIED
HE WAS GOING TO BE VIOLENT.
BUT GIVEN HIS AWKWARD SOCIAL
GRACES, THEY WERE WORRIED THAT
HE WOULD BE A VICTIM TO SOMEBODY
ELSE OR PERHAPS EVEN HURT
HIMSELF.
MEANWHILE, 25 MINUTES BEFORE THE
TOP OF THE HOUR.
OTHER HEADLINES ON THIS MONDAY,
ONE DAY AFTER THE NEWTOWN
SHOOTING, A MAN UNDER ARREST FOR
SHOOTING A SCHOOL MASSACRE IN
END IN.
POLICE FOUND 47 GUNS IN HIS
HOME, RIGHT NEXT O AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL WHERE HIS WIFE WORKS.
DURING A FIGHT, MYER ALLEGEDLY
THREATENED TO SET FIRE TO HIS
WIFE, THEN SAID HE WOULD GO TO
THE SCHOOL AND KILL AS MANY
PEOPLE AS POSSIBLE.
>> Gretchen: PRESIDENT OBAMA'S
$60 BILLION REQUEST FOR AID FOR
SANDY VICTIMS HAS TURNED INTO A
CHRISTMAS STOCK OF GOODIES FOR
FEDERAL AGENCIES AND EVEN NOW
THE STATE OF ALASKA.
IF YOU'RE SCRATCHING YOUR HEAD
TO FIGURE THAT OUT, HERE IT IS.
NEW YORK POST LEARNING IT
INCLUDED $150 MILLION TORE
FISHERIES IN ALASKA.
ALSO $41 MILLION FOR MILITARY
BASE, INCLUDING GITMO.
KENNEDY SPACE CENTER WHERE WORE
$40 MILLION FOR REPAIRS AND THE
SMITHSONIAN WOULD GET 2 MILLION.
REPUBLICANS SAY A VOTE ON THE
BILL WON'T HAPPEN UNTIL AFTER
CHRISTMAS BECAUSE OF A LACK OF
DETAILS ABOUT THE MEASURE.
BRIAN?
>> Brian: AFTER A TOUGH FEW
WEEKS, KATE MIDDLETON IS BACK IN
THE SPOTLIGHT.
HERE IS THE PREGNANT DUCHESS
BACK STAGE AT THE SPORTS
PERSONALITIES OF THE YEAR I
AWARDS.
THIS IS IN LONDON WHERE SHE WENT
TO DO AWARDS.
EARLIER THIS MONTH SHE WAS
HOSPITALIZED FOR SEVERE MORNING
SICKNESS.
SHE WASN'T FEELING WELL ENOUGH
TO STAY FOR THE ENTIRE FOUR HOUR
EHAVE NOT AND WENT HOME AFTER 45
MINUTES.
>> Gretchen: A MAN WHOSE DOG WAS
STOLEN HAS BEEN REUNITED REUNITH
THE BEACH.
GUESS HOW MANY YEARS.
FIVE YEARS LATER.
>> THAT'S SO COOL.
>> HE'S BEEN EVERYWHERE.
>> Gretchen: ANOTHER STORY TO
CRY ABOUT.
EMOTIONAL REUNION, A LONG TIME
COMING, THE MAN SAYS BANDIT HAD
RUN OUT OF HIS HOME AND A MAN
PICKED HIM UP AND DROVE OFF.
BUT HE WAS FOUND LAST MONTH AND
WAS SET TO BE EUTHANIZED AT A
SHELTER, SO HE WAS SENT TO
ANOTHER AND THAT'S WHERE THEY
FOUND OUT THAT HE HAD A
MICROCHIP.
AND THEY CONNECTED HIM BACK WITH
HIS HAPPY OWNER.
>> Steve: ANOTHER GOOD REASON TO
CHIP YOUR DOGS AND YOUR CATS.
MEANWHILE, 21 MINUTES BEFORE THE
TOP OF THE HOUR, LET'S LOOK AT
WHERE IT IS RAINING.
THERE IS A WHOLE BUNCH OF RAIN,
AS YOU CAN SEE, ACROSS THE
EASTERN HALF OF THE UNITED
STATES.
PORTIONS OF THE CENTRAL PLAINS
RIGHT NOW MOVING THROUGH THE
OZARKS.
HEAVY STUFF FROM LOUISIANA, UP
THROUGH PORTIONS OF ALABAMA
WHERE WE'VE GOT SOME
THUNDERSTORMS IN THE LAST COUPLE
OF HOURS, NOW MOVING INTO
PORTION OF GEORGIA AND SOUTH
CAROLINA.
STORM SYSTEM MOVES UP THROUGH
THE NORTHEAST AND WE HAVE SOME
SNOW CURRENTLY IN PORTIONS OF
NEW ENGLAND.
AS YOU CAN SEE, BEHIND THE FRONT
IT'S MUCH CHILLIER.
RIGHT NOW WE'VE ONLY GOT
21 DEGREES IN MINNEAPOLIS.
ABOUT THE SAME FOR DENVER,
ALBUQUERQUE.
WARMER THAN 25.
IN CARIBOU, MAINE, 14.
CHILLY.
41 NOW HERE IN THE BIG TOWN OF
NEW YORK CITY.
55 IN RALEIGH.
LET'S LOOK AT THE DAY AHEAD.
TEMPERATURE WISE, THINGS ARE
GOING TO WARM UP INTO THE 60S
ACROSS THE MID ATLANTA HISPANIC
ACROSS MUCH OF DIXIE LAND.
NORTHERN PLAINS, STILL PORTIONS
BELOW FREEZING.
SHOULD BE 63 LATER TODAY IN LOS
ANGELES.
AND IF YOU'RE OUT IN PROVO,
UTAH, GOOD MORNING.
YOUR DAYTIME HIGH WILL BE 44.
AND THAT'S A LOOK AT YOUR
WEATHER ON THIS MONDAY.
>> Gretchen: COMING UP, NEW TAX
THREATENING THOUSANDS OF JOBS,
EVEN DEMOCRATS WANT IT GONE.
SO IS THE PRESIDENT STILL
PUSHING FOR IT?
WE'LL EXPLAIN WHAT IT IS NEXT.
>> Brian: THEN HE WORKED YEARS
TO BUILD A SMALL BUSINESS AND IT
WAS DESTROYED IN MINUTES BY
ANGRY UNION PROTESTERS.
THE STORY HAS AN AWESOMEG
♪
[ Male Announcer ] CAMPBELL'S
GREEN BEAN CASSEROLE.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO
AND WITH MY BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CREDIT CARD,
I LOVE 'EM EVEN MORE.
I EARN 1% CASH BACK EVERYWHERE,
EVERTIME.
2% ON GROCERIES.
3% ON GAS.
AUTOMATICALLY.
NO HOOPS TO JUMP THROUGH.
THAT'S 1% BACK ON...
[ toy robot sounds ]
2% ON PUMPN PIE.
AND APPLE.
3% BACK ON 4 TRIPS
TO THE AIRPORT.
IT'S AS EASY AS..
-[ man ] 1...
-[ woman ] 2...
[ woman ] 3.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CARD.
APPLY ONLINE OR AT
A BANK OF AMERICA NEAR YOU.
>> Brian: NEW TAX THAT MAY CUT
OVER 20,000 NEW JOBS THAT GOES
INTO EFFECT JANUARY 1.
IT'S NOT NEW.
YOU SHOULD HAVE KNOWN.
THE MEDICAL DEVICE TAX, PART OF
OBAMACARE.
CREDIT PSYCHICS SAY IT NOT ONLY
THREATEN JOBS, BUT WILL SEVERELY
DIMINISH MEDICAL TECHNOLOGY AS
WELL AS INNOVATION.
A GROUP LAWMAKERS, INCLUDING
DEMOCRATS, ARE DEMANDING IT BE
DELAYED.
JOINING US IS CONGRESSMAN ERIC
PAUL, CO-CHAIR OF THE MEDICAL
CAUCUS WHERE.  HAVE THEY BEEN ON
THIS?
>> I TELL YOU TEXAS RANGERS
GREAT TO HAVE THE SUPPORT OF
SOME DEMOCRAT SENATORS OF
RECENT, BUT THE HOUSE PASSED
THIS BILL SIX MONTHS AGO AND
IT'S A TICKING TIME BOMB.
WE'VE GOT 16 DAYS TO STOP THIS
DEVASTATING TAX ON SOME OF OUR
BEST JOB CREATORS.
>> Brian: HOW WOULD A TAX ON
MEDICAL DEVICES AFFECT JOBS?
>> I TELL YOU, ONLY IN
WASHINGTON WOULD YOU IMPOSE A
TAX ON THIS INDUSTRY AND THINK
YOU'RE GOING TO SAVE HEALTH CARE
COSTS.
HERE IS WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN,
THIS IS A TAX ON REVENUE.
IT'S NOT A TAX ON PROFIT.
SO YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE FEWER
START-UPS.
THIS IS ONE OF OUR BEST AMERICAN
SUCCESS STORIES.
AND NOW BIG COMPANIES ARE GOING
TO START LAYING PEOPLE OFF,
WHICH THEY'RE DOING.
THEY'RE MOVING JOBS OVERSEAS,
THEY'RE CURTAILING THEIR
INVESTMENTS IN RESEARCH AND
DEVELOPMENT.
IT'S NOT A GOOD MESSAGE TO BE
SEND NOT GUILTY A TOUGH ECONOMY.
>> Brian: GIVE US AN IDEA.
THESE ARE PACE MAKERS, RIGHT?
OBVIOUSLY ARTIFICIAL HEARTS.
EVERYTHING THAT MADE AMERICA THE
PLACE TO GO WHEN YOU NEEDED A
COMPLICATED SURGICAL PROCEDURE.
>> THAT'S ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
IN FACT, THIS IS TRULY AN
AMERICAN SUCCESS STORY.
LESS INVASIVE SURGERIES.
AN INDUSTRY CREDITED FOR
ENHANCING AND PROMOTING SAVING
LIVES FROM HEART DISEASE,
DIABETES, MANY OTHER DISEASES.
FUTURE TREATMENTS AS WELL.
SO THIS NOT ONLY SENDS A BAD
SIGNAL FOR SOME OF OUR BEST JOB
CREATORS, IT'S ALSO GOING TO
MAKE IT A LOT MORE DIFFICULT FOR
AMERICAN PATIENTS TO ACCESS
THESE NEW TECHNOLOGIES, CUTTING
AND LDING EDGE TECHNOLOGIES.
>> Brian: IS IT POSSIBLE PEOPLE
IN WASHINGTON DON'T UNDERSTAND
HOW THAT COULD AFFECT JOBS, HOW
IT WON'T NECESSARILY RESULT IN
INCREASED REVENUE?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
THERE IS ACTUALLY GOING TO BE A
DECLINE OVERALL.
THE PRESIDENT CLAIMED THIS IS
GOING TO BE A WINDFALL FOR THESE
DEVICE COMPANIES WITH SO MANY
PEOPLE COMING IN TO THE
INSURANCE MARKET.
THAT IS JUST A CONVENIENT MYTH.
IF YOU LOOKED AT STUDIES DONE,
FOR INSTANCE, EVEN IN
MASSACHUSETTS THAT HAS A SIMILAR
PROVISION TO OBAMACARE WITH THE
INDIVIDUAL MANDATE, THERE HAS
BEEN NO INCREASE IN UTILIZATION
WHATSOEVER.
>> Brian: PRESIDENT OBAMA ON
THIS MEDICAL DEVICE TAX SAYS
THIS:  THE HEALTH CARE BILL IS
GOING TO PROVIDE THOSE HEALTH
CARE COMPANIES 30 MILLION NEW
CUSTOMERS.
IT'S GOING TO BE GREAT FOR
BUSINESS.
THEY'RE DOING REALLY WELL RIGHT
NOW AND THEY'RE GOING TO GET
30 MILLION MORE CUSTOMERS AS A
CONSEQUENCE.
SO THIS TAX COMES BACK TO THEM
AS NEW CUSTOMERS.
SOUND LOGICAL TO YOU?
>> IT DOES NOT SOUND LOGICAL.
IT'S FICTION.
IT'S FALSE.
BOY, TELL THAT MESSAGE TO THE
FOLKS AND THE EMPLOYEES LAID OFF
FROM THESE COMPANIES OR THAT ARE
LOSING JOBS, MOVING OVERSEAS.
THAT'S NOT THE MESSAGE THEY WANT
TO HEAR.
WE NEED TO BE DOING THE OPPOSITE
AND STOP THIS TAX BEFORE IT
STARTS ON JANUARY 1.
>> Brian: AMAZING.
IF YOU ASK FOR A DELAY, THAT
MEANS YOU DON'T WANT IT AND YOU
REALIZE THE CONSEQUENCES, YOU
WANT TO SAVE YOUR OWN POLITICAL
CAREER.
CONGRESSMAN, THANKS SO MUCH.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH, BRIAN.
>> Brian: FINALLY, A MOVIE THE
WHOLE FAMILY CAN SEE.
IT'S NOT "HERE COMES THE BOOM."
THE ACTOR EVERYONE IS TALKING
ABOUT IS HERE AND SHE IS JUST 13
YEARS OLD AND THIS MOVIE WAS
PHENOMENAL.
THEN HE WORKED FOR YEARS TO
BUILD HIS BUSINESS.
UNION PROTESTERS DESTROYED IT IN
JUST MINUTES.
BUT IT'S A STORY THAT WILL MAKE
YOU SMILE.
FIRST, LET'S CHECK IN WITH BILL
HEM WHO ARE DID SUCH AN
INCREDIBLE JOB IN CONNECTICUT
OVER THE WEEKEND.
HE'S STILL THERE NOW AND WILL
TELL US WHAT'S COMING UP AT THE
TOP OF THE HOUR.
HEY, BILL.
>> BRIAN, GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
TOUGH DAYS FOR ALL OF US ALL
ACROSS THE COUNTRY, FRANKLY.
WE ARE MINUTES AWAY FROM SEEING
THE FIRST POLICE BRIEFING OF THE
DAY.
WE'LL SEE LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE
FROM THE CONNECTICUT POLICE
DEPARTMENT.
WE WILL CARRY THAT LIVE FOR YOU
WHEN IT GETS UNDERWAY AND A
TERRIFIC LINE - UP OF GUESTS TO
HELP US GET TO THE WHY AND ALL
OF THIS.
MARTHA AND I WILL CONTINUE OUR
COVERAGE RIGHT AFTER YOU AT THE
TOP OF THE HOUR.
ALSO, TWO FUNERALS FOR TWO
SIX-YEAR-OLD BOYS TODAY.
WE ARE LIVE IN SANDY HOOK ON
THIS SCHOOL TRAGEDY AT THE TOP
OF THE HOUR.
finished a bowl ofr
new Light Chicken Pot Pie Soup
and it's so rich
and creamy...
is it really 100 calories?
Let me put you on webcan...
...lean roasted chicken...
and a creamy broth
Mmm
I can still see you.
[ Male announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
[ coughs ]
[ baby crying ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
ROBITUSSIN® LIQUID FORMULA
SOOTHES YOUR THROAT ON CONTACT
AND THE ACTIVE INGREDIENT
RELIEVES YOUR COUGH.
ROBITUSSIN®. DON'T SUFFER
THE COUGHEQUENCES™.
Meet the 5-passenger
Ford C-MAX Hybrid.
AND THE ACTIVE INGREDIENT
RELIEVES YOUR COUGH.
When you're carrying
a lot of weight,
C-MAX has a nice little trait,
You see, C-MAX helps
you load your freight,
with its foot-activated
lift gate.
But that's not
all you'll see,
Cause C-MAX also
beats Prius v,
with better MPG.
Say hi to the all-new 47
combined MPG C-MAX Hybrid.
>> Steve: QUICK HEADLINES.
UNION WORKERS DESTROYED HIS
FAMOUS HOT DOG CART DURING THE
RIGHT TO WORK PROTEST IN
MICHIGAN A COUPLE WEEKS AGO.
BUT SUPPORTERS SET UP A FUND FOR
THAT MAN, CLINTON TARVER AND
THEY RAISED $33,000 FOR HIM TO
BUY A NEW CART.
THAT'S GREAT.
>>> AND PRESIDENT BUSH'S PICK UP
IS BEING AUCTIONED OFF FOR
CHARITY NEXT MONTH.
HE STARTED DRIVING THE FORD BACK
IN 2009 AROUND HIS RANCH DOWN IN
TEXAS.
THE AUTOGRAPHED -- HE
AUTOGRAPHED THE AIR BAG, IF
THAT'S POSSIBLE.
MEANWHILE, OLD SCHOOL MEETS NEW
SCHOOL IN THE NEW MOVIE
"PARENTAL GUIDANCE."
LOOK AT THIS.
>> THE JOKES THAT YOU WON'T GET.
SO JUST LAUGH.
JUST LAUGH.
I PROMISE YOU, WE WILL GET
THROUGH THIS WEEK.
>> HELLO BOYS, STILL SINGLE?
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Gretchen: WED INTO SOMETHING
TO LAUGH ABOUT.
THE A LIST STARS HAVE MET THEIR
MATCH IN 13-YEAR-OLD BAILEY
MADISON AND REJOINS US -- SHE'S
BEEN ON BEFORE.
YOU'RE IN THIS GREAT MOVIE THAT
OPENS ON CHRISTMAS DAY.
>> YES, I AM.
IT'S NICE TO BE BACK.
>> Steve: YOU'RE WEARING GREEN
TODAY AS A LOT OF PEOPLE TO
COMMEMORATE THE LIVES OF THE
CHILDREN LOST AT SANDY HOOK.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
I AM BEYOND HEART BROKEN FOR
WHAT IS GOING ON AND MY THOUGHTS
AND MY PRAYERS GO OUT TO ALL
THOSE AFFECTED AND INVOLVED.
WHILE I'M TRAVELING SPREADING
THIS JOY OF THIS MOVIE THAT IS
PERFECT FOR ALL HOLIDAY SEASON,
MUCH NEEDED RIGHT NOW, HOPEFULLY
I CAN GIVE A BIT OF A SMILE.
>> Steve: YOU WERE TELLING US
EARLIER THAT THE STORIES OF
HEROISM REGARDING SOME OF THESE
TEACHERS WHO DID THEIR BEST TO
SAVE THE LIVERS -- LIVES OF
THEIR CHILDREN REMINDED YOU OF
SOME OF YOUR SCHOOL TEACHERS.
>> I GREW UP IN A SCHOOL LIKE
THIS ONE.
AND I COULD IMAGINE SOME MIFF
TEACHERS DOING WHAT THEY COULD
TO SAVE US.
I'M TRULY TAKEN BACK AND JUST
WE'RE JUST ALL BLESSED.
VERY UNFORTUNATE.
>> Brian: TELL BUS THIS MOVIE.
WE SAW THE PROCEED KNOWS.
-- PROMOS.
>> IT'S ABOUT NEW SCHOOL MEETS
OLD SCHOOL.
GRANDPARENTS COME TO VISIT US
AND OUR PARENTS HAVE THEIR OWN
WAY OF PARENTING, LIKE YOU DON'T
USE THE WORD NO, FOR INSTANCE.
THEY KIND INVEST TO COME IN AND
WHIP US BACK IN SHAPE.
AND IT'S JUST A FILM FOR THE
ENTIRE FAMILY TO MAKE YOU LAUGH
DURING THE HOLIDAYS, BRING YOU
CLOSE TO ONE ANOTHER AND JUST
PUTTING OUT A GOOD AND POSITIVE
MESSAGE.
>> Gretchen: LET'S TAKE A LOOK
AT ONE OF THE FUNNY CLIPS.
>> THANK YOU.
>> THAT'S NOT BAD.
>> NOT BAD?
SHE LOOKS LIKE A 12-YEAR-OLD
WIDOW.
>> I DO?
>> WHAT ABOUT THIS?
PERFECT FOR SOMEONE A CUTE
LITTLE HINEY.
>> I LOVE IT.
>> MOM, IT'S FOR A CONCERT.
NOT TO MEET THE FLEET.
>> HEY, IT'S AN AUDITION.
ALL AUDITIONS ARE ALIKE.
GET THEIR ATTENTION!
THAT'S HOW I GOT ALL THOSE
WEATHER GIRL JOBS.
>> ARE YOU LIKE A TRAINED
UROLOGIST?
>> TRAINED?
I HAD A TIGHT DRESS AND A
POINTER.
I USED TO SING MY FORECASTS.
AS A MATTER OF FACT, SOMETIMES
YOUR MOM USED TO SING THEM WITH
ME ON TV.
>> Gretchen: SO MANY PARENTS ARE
GOING TO BE ABLE TO RELATE TO
THIS BECAUSE FOR MY PARENTS OUT
THERE, LOVE YOU, BUT THEY'RE
LESS STRICT WITH MY KIDS THAN
THEY WERE WITH ME.
>> YEAH.
IT'S SO FUNNY BECAUSE I AM LIKE
THE SUPER UPTIGHT TEEN-AGER,
LIKE EVERYTHING HAS TO GO AS
PLANNED.
I HAVE TO DO MY BEST TO MAKE
EVERYTHING GO SMOOTHIE.
IT'S MADE TRYING TO LET LOOSE
AND BE THE FUN SIDE OF LOOKING
AT MY GRANDMA SAYING, I WANT TO
BE LIKE HER.
>> Steve: NEW GENERATION OF
PARENTS, THEY'RE KIND OF LIKE,
WITH TEE BALL, EVERYBODY GETS A
RIBBON.
EVERYBODY IS A WINNER.
>> AND IT'S SO FUNNY BECAUSE
PARENTS PARENT LIKE THAT.
>> Steve: THEY DO.
>> IT'S SO RELATABLE AND IT'S
PERFECT FOR EVERYONE,  WHICH IS
GREAT TO BE ABLE TO GO TO A
MOVIE REMEMBER THAT.
>> Brian: THE LIGHTS ARE DIM,
THE CAMERAS ARE OFF, YOU'RE
HANGING OUT WITH BETTE MIDLER
AND BILLY CRYSTAL.
THAT'S LIKE?
>> THEY'RE INCREDIBLE.
>> Brian: WHO DO YOU LIKE
BETTER?
>> Steve: YOU GOT TO PICK.
>> I LIKE BETTE AS A GIRL AND
BILLY AS A BOY.
THEY'RE BOTH WONDERFUL.
THAT IS A CLASS ACT AND BILLY IS
JUST SUCH A TALENT.
>> Steve: YOU START WITH THE B,
TOO, BAILEY MADISON.
CHECK OUT THE MOVIE, OPENS
CHRISTMAS DAY.
>> PLEASE DO.
TAKE YOUR FAMILY.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Steve: MERRY CHRISTMAS.
>> Gretchen: MORE "FOX &
FRIENDS" TWO MINUTES AWAY.
[ engine revs ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THE MERCEDES-BENZ WINTER EVENT
IS BACK,
WITH THE PERFECT VEHICLE
THAT'S JUST RIGHT FOR YOU,
. .
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
ML350 FOR $599 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
>> Brian: YOU'RE LOOKING LIVE AT
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT WHERE
LIEUTENANT VANCE IS ABOUT TO
GIVE AN UPDATE ON THEIR
INVESTIGATION INTO THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
WE'LL BRING IT TO YOU LIVE WHEN
IT HAPPENS.
>> Steve: AND THIS AS A FIRST OF
THE YOUNG VICTIMS ARE LAID TO
REST LATER ON TODAY.
WE WANT TO LOOK AT THOSE WHO
WERE TAKEN TOO EARLY.
>> Gretchen: SO WE KEEP THEM IN
OUR THOUGHTS AND OUR PRAYERS,
ALONG WITH THEIR FRIENDS AND
FAMILIES.
AND AS THE PRESIDENT SAID, YOU
ARE NOT ALONE IN YOUR GRIEF.