ENTITLEMENTS AND SPENDING ON
THE ENTITLEMENTS.
THAT'S JUST NOT SOMETHING OUR
FRAMERS THOUGHT ABOUT
BECAUSE -- WE DIDN'T HAVE A
WELFARE STATE IN THOSE DAYS.
>> GLEN, ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
>> I'M FINE.
>> OKAY, GOOD.
APOLOGIZE FOR THAT BY THE WAY.
>> I LOVE LIVE TV.
>> THAT'S OKAY.
THAT'S WHAT HAPPENS WHEN YOU
CRITICIZE THE WELFARE STATE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Bret: THERE YOU GO.
THANKS FOR INVITING US INTO
YOUR HOME TONIGHT.
THAT IS IT FOR THIS "SPECIAL
REPORT," FAIR, BALANCED AND
UNAFRAID.
>> THIS IS THE FOX REPORT.
TONIGHT, MORE FALLOUT FROM THE
ATTACK IN BENGHAZI.
U.N. AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE IS
OUT AS THE NEXT SECRETARY OF
STATE.
SO WHO WILL REPLACE HILLARY
CLINTON?
AND A FORMER UNITED STATES
MARINE LOCKED UP IN MEXICO.
>> RIGHT WHEN HE CROSSED THE
BORDER.
STILL, THE MEXICAN POLICE PUT
HIM BEHIND BARS FOR CARRYING A
GUN AND THEY HAVE LEFT HIM
LOCKED UP FOR MONTHS.
>> HE IS TOUGH.
SOMEBODY IS MAKING EXTORTION
DEMANDS AND THAT SAY IT'S TIME
TO BRING THEIR SON HOME.
SOFTWARE MOGUL JOHN McAFEE
ON THE RUN FROM THE LAW NOW
BACK IN THE UNITED STATES AND
AS USUAL HE HAS PLENTY TO SAY.
>> I DON'T THINK ANYBODY
THINKS I MURDERED MY NEIGHBOR,
EXCEPT YOU, THE PRESS.
>> I HAVE TONS OF EVIDENCE
ABOUT THE CORRUPTION, THE
HARASSMENT.
IF YOU EVER EVER TASTED
GUATEMALA JAIL FOOD IT'S NOT
VERY NICE AND I WOULD LIKE
SOME SUSHI.
>> Harris: AFTER THAT WHOLE
HEART ATTACK THING YEAH,
MCAFEE HAS A CONFESSION ABOUT
THAT.
>> THE PLOT AGAINST HOT STAR
JUSTIN BIEBER.
WORD OF A PLAN THAT INVOLVES
KIDNAPPING.
MULTIPLE MURDER AND CASTRATION
BY SHEARS.
>> RACING A HORSE.
WAIT UNTIL YOU SEE HOW IT
ENDED.
I'M HARRIS FAULKNER IN TONIGHT
FOR SHEPARD SMITH.
UNITED NATIONS AMBASSADOR
SUSAN RICE IS OUT OF THE
RUNNING.
TO BE THE NEXT SECRETARY OF
STATE.
SHE ASKED PRESIDENT OBAMA TO
TAKE HER OFF THE LIST AND HE
SAYS HE HAS ACCEPTED HER
DECISION.
BUT HE IS BLASTING HER
REPUBLICAN CRITICS FOR WHAT HE
CALLS UNFAIR AND MISLEADING
ATTACKS ON RICE.
SOME REPUBLICAN SENATORS THREB
TO BLOCK RICE'S
BECAUSE OF HER COMMENTS ABOUT
THAT ATTACK ON THE OUTPOST IN
BENGHAZI.
TERRORISTS KILLED OUR U.S.
AMBASSADOR TO IT LIBYA CHRIS
STEVENS AND THREE OTHER
AMERICANS ON SEPTEMBER 11TH OF
THIS YEAR.
THREE DAYS LATER AMBASSADOR
RICE WENT ON THE TALK SHOW
CIRCUIT AND SAID SEVERAL TIMES
U.S. OFFICIALS BELIEVED THE
VIOLENCE WAS A SPONTANEOUS
REACTION OVER PROTESTS TO
ANTI-MUSLIM VIDEO NOT A
PREPLANNED TERRORIST ATTACK.
INTELLIGENCE OFFICIALS SAY
THEY GAVE HER THOSE TALKING
POINTS BUT THOSE OPPONENTS DID
NOT BACK DOWN AND TODAY
AMBASSADOR RICE SENT THE
LETTER TO THE PRESIDENT,
QUOTE:  I AM NOW CONVINCED
THAT THE CONFIRMATION PROCESS
WOULD BE LENGTHY, DISRUPTIVE
AND COSTLY TO YOU AND TO OUR
MOST PRESSING NATIONAL AND
INTERNATIONAL PRIORITIES.
THAT TRADEOFF IS SIMPLY NOT
WORTH IT TO OUR COUNTRY, END
QUOTE.
WE HAVE TEAM FOX COVERAGE NOW.
CATHERINE HERRIDGE IS LIVE ON
CAPITOL HILL WHERE LAWMAKERS
GOT ANOTHER CLASSIFIED
BRIEFING ON BENGHAZI TODAY.
FIRST THOUGH TO ED HENRY LIVE
AT THE WHITE HOUSE.
ED, WHAT'S THE REACTION THERE?
GOOD EVENING, HARRIS.
THERE IS DISAPPOINTMENT HERE
BECAUSE I SAID OVER THE
DECISION LAST FEW DAYS, HE
WANTED SUSAN RICE TO
AMBASSADOR UP TO SECRETARY OF
STATE.
HE KNEW IT WOULD BE TOO MUCH
OF A BRUISING BATTLE, NOT JUST
THREATENED FILIBUSTER FROM
CONSERVATIVE REPUBLICANS LIKE
JOHN MCCAIN AND LYNSEY GRAM,
COLLINS WHO WOULD BE LIKELY TO
SUPPORT THE PRESIDENT'S
NOMINEES SAID SHE WAS TROUBLED
BY THE POTENTIAL NOMINATION.
THE PRESIDENT TRIED TO PUT THE
BEST FACE ON THIS IN A
STATEMENT WHERE HE SAID,
QUOTE:  I HAVE EVERY
CONFIDENCE THAT SUSAN WAS
LIMITLESS CAPABILITY TO SERVE
OUR COUNTRY NOW AND IN THE
YEARS TO COME.
IN FACT, WE'RE TOLD SHE IS
EXPECTED TO AT LEAST STAY ON
AS U.N. AMBASSADOR IF NOT TAKE
ANOTHER POSITION.
SUSAN RICE, BY THE WAY, IN
THAT LETTER TO THE PRESIDENT,
WENT ON TO SAY, QUOTE:  WE
CANNOT AFFORD SUCH AN
IRRESPONSIBLE DISTRACTION FROM
THE MOST PRESSING ISSUES
FACING THE AMERICAN PEOPLE.
THERE IS NO DOUBT THAT SHE WAS
REFERRING NOT JUST TO THE
THREATENED FILIBUSTER BUT THE
FACT THAT WE HAVE A WHOLE HOST
OF INTERNATIONAL ISSUES AS
WELLS THE PRESIDENT IN THE
MIDDLE OF THESE VERY TENSE
BUDGET NEGOTIATIONS AS WELL,
HARRIS.
>> Harris: AND SOME ACTIVITY
ABOUT THE GROUP THAT SURROUNDS
THE PRESIDENT AS A CABINET.
WE UNDERSTAND THAT THIS IS
JUST A FIRST IN SERIES OF
MOVES.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
TOP DEMOCRATS ARE TELLING ME
THAT CHUCK HAGEL, THE FORMER
REPUBLIC SENATOR IS NOW THE
LEADING CONTENDER TO BECOME
THE NEXT DEFENSE SECRETARY.
LEON PANETTA EXPECTED TO STEP
DOWN IN THE BOOKS AHEAD.
INTERESTING BECAUSE IT COULD
GIVE THE PRESIDENT
BIPARTISANSHIP IN THE CAB
NEVMENT ALSO WHAT'S
INTERESTING IS THAT THERE
MIGHT BE A WHOLE SERIES OF
OTHER SHUFFLES.
I'M TOLD SHE IS BEING LOOKED
AT FOR NATIONAL SECURITY
ADVISOR INSIDE THE WHITE
HOUSE.
THE KEY BEING SHE WOULDN'T
NEED SENATE CONFIRMATION.
REPUBLICANS COULD NOT
FILIBUSTER IT.
SHE WOULD REPLACE TOM DONILIN
BY THE WAY.
SOME PEOPLE TALKING HIM UP TO
BE WHITE HOUSE CHIEF OF STAFF.
THE CURRENT CHIEF OF STAFF
THERE JACK LEW MIGHT BECOME
THE TREASURY SECRETARY.
SO BASICALLY IT'S A GAME OF
MUSICAL CHAIRS,.
>> Harris: HAIRS BACK TO
HILLARY CLINTON LEAVING.
IF IT ISN'T AMBASSADOR RICE
SENATOR JOHN KERRY SAID TO BE
ON A SHORT LIST AS WELL AND
MAYBE A FRONTRUNNER.
>> IS HE ALL BUT THE NOMINEE
AT THIS POINT WHEN YOU TALK TO
TOP DEMOCRATS.
THEY HAVE GONE THROUGH THE
VETTING.
IS HE SOMEBODY WHO A MEMBER OF
THE SENATE CLUB.
SO HE IS LIKELY TO BE
CONFIRMED.
WOULDN'T HAVE THE SAME
TROUBLES AS SUSAN RICE.
ONE POTENTIAL ROD ROAD BLOCK
SCOTT BROWN.
IF JOHN KERRY DOES BECOME
SECRETARY OF STATE THAT OPENS
UP THE SEAT THERE WOULD BE A
SPECIAL ELECTION.
SCOTT BROWN LIKELY TO RUN.
SOME DEMOCRATS TONIGHT NERVOUS
THAT THEY COULD GAIN A NEW
SECRETARY OF STATE IN JOHN
KERRY BUT LOSE THAT SENATE
SEAT IN MASSACHUSETTS.
BOTTOM LINE THE WHITE HOUSE
MADE A BIGGER POLITICAL
CALCULATION TONIGHT, HARRIS,
THEY DID NOT WANT TO START
THIS SECOND TERM OFF WITH A
MESSY BATTLE OVER BENGHAZI.
>> Harris: THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
ONE U.S. OFFICIAL SAYS THE
STATE DEPARTMENT MAY NOT HE
RELEASE THE REPORT ON ITS OWN
BENGHAZI NEGOTIATION.
TEAM FOX COVERAGE CONTINUES
NOW.
CATHERINE HERRIDGE LIVE FOR US
ON CAPITOL HILL.
DOES THE DEPARTMENT HAVE TO
RELEASE THAT REPORT?
>> WELL, THANK YOU, HARRIS AND
GOOD EVENING.
TONIGHT FOX NEWS HAS REVIEWED
THE REGULATIONS HERE.
THERE ARE 15 PAGES LONG THAT
GOVERNOR THE STATE
DEPARTMENT'S INTERRIBLE
INVESTIGATION THERE DOES NOT
APPEAR TO BE A REQUIREMENT FOR
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON TO GIVE THE ENTIRE
REPORT TO CONGRESS.
THERE ONLY SEEMS TO BE A
REQUIREMENT FOR THE SECRETARY
TO PROVIDE A WRITTEN SUM TROY
CONGRESS FINDINGS OF THE
REPORT SO WE MAY BE LOOKING AT
ANOTHER LOOMING BATTLE GIVING
THAT ENTIRE REPORT HERE TO
CAPITOL HILL, HARRIS.
>> YOU SEE SECRETARY CLINTON
IN VIDEO THERE.
CONFLICTING REPORTS TODAY
ABOUT WHETHER OR NOT SHE WOULD
ACTUALLY TESTIFY ON CAPITOL
HILL AT THIS POINT.
>> WE HAD A WHOLE BACK AND
FORTH TODAY WITH TWO
CONGRESSIONAL COMMITTEES
SAYING THAT THEY EXPECT
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON TO BE HERE ON CAPITOL
HILL A WEEK TODAY FOR AT LEAST
ONE PLUCK HEARING INTO THE
PUBLIC HEARING INTO THE AGAIN
BENGHAZI NEGOTIATION.
EARLIER TODAY STATE DEPARTMENT
TOLD REPORTERS THAT MAY BE
FLEXIBLE BECAUSE INTERNAL
REVIEW CALLED THE ACCOUNTABLE
REVIEW BOARD OR ARB IS NOT
FINISHED.
>> THE ARB IS KIN CONTINUING
TO DO ITS WORK TO MY
KNOWLEDGE, IT HAS NOT YET
CONCLUDED ITS WORK.
AS YOU KNOW, IT'S DECIDED TO
KEEP ITS DELIBERATIONS
CONFIDENTIAL UNTIL IT IS
FINISHED.
AS WE HAVE BEEN SAYING, OUR
EXPECTATION IS THAT AFTER THE
ARB REPORTS TO THE SECRETARY,
THEN SHE WILL HAVE
CONSULTATIONS WITH CONGRESS.
>> Harris: ONE CONGRESSIONAL
STAFF TOLD FOX THIS EVENING
THAT IN FACT THE SITUATION
DOES APPEAR VERY FLUID AND
THAT IF THINGS MOVE A LITTLE
BIT MORE QUICKLY THEY COULD
SEE THE SECRETARY OF STATE UP
HERE ON CAPITOL HILL BEFORE
THURSDAY, HARRIS.
>> Harris: CAPITOL HILL A BUSY
PLACE FOR CLASSIFIED
BRIEFINGS.
ANOTHER ONE TODAY.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
WE HAD TWO CLOSED CLASSIFIED
BRIEFINGS.
ONE BEFORE THE HOUSE
INTELLIGENCE COMMITTEE.
THE SECOND BEFORE THE SENATE
FOX NEWS WAS TOLD LAWMAKERS
WERE IN ESSENCE GIVEN IN THAT
BRIEFING AN ASSESSMENT OF THE
INVESTIGATION HAS BEEN PRETTY
SLOW-GOING.
IN PART BECAUSE THE LIBYAN
GOVERNMENT, FOR EXAMPLE, DOES
NOT HAVE CONTROL OVER THE
EASTERN PART OF BENGHAZI
WHERE -- EASTERN PART OF LIBYA
WHERE YOU FIND BENGHAZI.
THAT'S RATHER IN THE CONTROL
OF THE MILITIAS.
ONE LEADING DEMOCRAT
CHARACTERIZED THE PROGRESS AS
LIMITED.
>> WELL, THERE IS STILL A LOT
MORE TO DO.
FACTS NOW WE ARE USING OUR
TECHNIQUES AND USING OUR
RELATIONSHIPS WITH OTHER
GOVERNMENTS TO FIND OUT WHO
DID IN AND WHY THEY DID IT.
EARLIER THIS WEEK THE ATTORNEY
GENERAL ERIC HOLDER WAS ASKED
BY FOX FOR HIS ASSESSMENT FBI
INVESTIGATION INTO RESPONSE TO
CLAIMS THAT IT SEEMED SOMEWHAT
SLOW OR STALLED.
HE SAID THERE HAS BEEN A LOT
OF THE PROGRESS.
JUST SOME OF IT IS HAPPENING
BEHIND THE SCENES, HARRIS.
>> CATHERINE HERRIDGE
REPORTING BEHIND THE SCENES.
THANK YOU.
IN AFGHANISTAN NOW.
A BOMBER BLEW HIMSELF UP IN AN
ATTACK THAT LEFT ONE U.S.
SOLDIER DEAD AND WOUNDED
SEVERAL OTHERS IT HAPPENED
SHORTLY AFTER A VISIT FROM
DEFENSE SECRETARY LEON PA NET
ATTACHMENT THE ATTACK
HAPPENING NEAR KANDAHAR AIR
FIELD IN THE SOUTHERN PART OF
THE COUNTRY.
THE DEFENSE SECRETARY HAS
VISITED THAT AIR FIELD JUST
LESS THAN THREE HOURS EARLIER.
HIS SPOKESPERSON SAYS THERE IS
NO SIGN THE ATTACKER WAS
TRYING TO TARGET HIM.
DEFENSE SECRETARY PANETTA ALSO
MEETING WITH AFGHAN PRESIDENT
HARMID KARZAI IN AFGHANISTAN
AND ANNOUNCING THAT NEXT MONTH
PRESIDENT KARZAI WILL COME TO
THE UNITED STATES TO MEET WITH
PRESIDENT OBAMA ABOUT THE
FUTURE OF THE U.S. PRESENCE IN
THAT COUNTRY.
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER
MEETING WITH PRESIDENT OBAMA
TONIGHT TO TRY TO WORK OUT A
WAY TO KEEP THE COUNTRY FROM
FALLING OFF THE SO-CALLED
FISCAL CLIFF.
THEIR SITDOWN WRAPPING UP A
SHORT TIME AGO.
WE WILL TAKE YOU LIVE BACK TO
CAPITOL HILL FOR AN UPDATE ON
THEIR PROGRESS.
PLUS, FORMER PRESIDENT GEORGE
H.W. BUSH HAS BEEN IN THE
HOSPITAL NOW FOR WEEKS.
AND WITH CHRISTMAS COMING UP,
YOU KNOW HE HAS TO BE ITCHING
TO GET HOME.
WE'LL TELL YOU WHAT THE
DOCTORS ARE SAYING ABOUT THAT.
STAY CLOSE.
♪
[ engine revs ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THE MERCEDES-BENZ WINTER EVENT
IS BACK,
WITH THE PERFECT VEHICLE
THAT'S JUST RIGHT FOR YOU,
NO MATTER WHICH LIST YOU'RE ON.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
ML350 FOR $599 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
LOOK THIS ISN'T
MY FIRST CHRISTMAS.
THESE DEALS ALL SEEM GREAT
AT THE TIME...
BUT LATER...
[ shirt ]
MERRY CHRISTMAS, EVERYBODY!
NOT SO MUCH.
HO HO HO!
THIS ISN'T
THAT KIND OF DEAL.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SAVE ON GROUND SHIPPING
AT FEDEX OFFICE.
CAMPBELL'S HAS 24 NEW SOUPS
THAT WILL MAKE IT DROP OVER,
AND OVER AGAIN.
♪
FROM JAMMIN' JERK CHICKEN,
TO CREAMY GOUDA BISQUE.
SEE WHAT'S NEW FROM CAMPBELL'S.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
>> A SHORT TIME AGO WE WATCHED
AND REPORTED AS IT WAS
HAPPENING ON HOUSE SPEAKER
JOHN BOEHNER MAKING THE
10-MINUTE OR SO DRIVE TO THE
WHITE HOUSE TO MEET WITH THE
PRESIDENT FOR THE SECOND TIME
THIS WEEK.
JUST 19 DAYS TO GO UNTIL THEY
ARE SET TO OR WE'RE SET TO
PLUNGE OFF THE SO-CALLED
FISCAL CLIFF.
BUT WHO KNOWS IF THIS ACTUALLY
GETS US ANY CLOSER TO A DEAL.
TO STOP THAT FROM HAPPENING.
ECONOMISTS WARNING THE
COMBINATION OF TAX HIKES AND
SPENDING CUTS KICKING IN ON
NEW YEAR'S DAY COULD SEND US
INTO ANOTHER RESCISSION.
MIKE ON CAPITOL HILL NOW.
WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT TONIGHT
WANT MEETING.
>> HARRIS, WE'RE TOLD IT WAS
50 MINUTES LONG.
BOTH SIDES IT WAS FRANK AND
WON'T BE ANY FURTHER READOUT
MEETING AND LINES OF
COMMUNICATION REMAIN OPEN.
EARLIER THIS THE DAY IT WAS
NOT SO COOPERATIVE.
IN FACT, SPEAKER BOEHNER WAS
QUITE CRITICAL OF THE WHITE
HOUSE.
>> UNFORTUNATELY THE WHITE
HOUSE IS SO UNSERIOUS ABOUT
CUTTING SPENDING THAT IT
APPEARS WILLING TO SLOW WALK
ANY AGREEMENT AND WALK OUR
ECONOMY RIGHT UP TO THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
>> NOW THE ADMINISTRATION
OFFICIAL TELLS US THAT
TREASURY SECRETARY TIM
GEITHNER WAS A PARTICIPANT IN
THAT 50 MINUTE MEETING IN THE
OVAL OFFICE WITH THE PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED STATES AND THE
SPEAKER IN THE HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES.
HARRIS?
>> Harris: THERE IS
PROCEDURALLY A LOT HA HAS TO
BE DONE TO PUT ANYTHING THEY
WOULD DECIDE ON INTO MOTION.
TOP DEMOCRATS ARE SUGGESTING
TIME MAY BE RUNNING OUT TO DO
WHAT THEY CALL A GRAND BARGAIN
AND THAT THEY MIGHT NEED TO
COME UP WITH A PLAN B.
>> THAT IS TRUE ALTHOUGH
PRESIDENT OBAMA DID AN
INTERVIEW WITH AN AFFILIATE IN
MINNEAPOLIS, WCCO AND SAYS HE
IS STILL OPTIMISTIC THAT THIS
CAN GET DONE.
HE SAYS HE IS OPEN TO MORE
SPENDING CUTS AND WOULD LIKE
TO PAIR IT WITH REVENUES SO WE
SHALL SEE.
EARLIER IN THE DAY THE WHITE
HOUSE PRESS SECRETARY
ESSENTIALLY SAID THIS COULD BE
A PLAN B.
>>
>> IN CASE OF EMERGENCY, THE
HOUSE SHOULD BREAK THE GLASS,
THE HOUSE SPEAKER OUGHT TO
ALLOW THE REPUBLICANS TO VOTE
ON EXTENDING TAX CUTS FOR 98%
OF THE AMERICAN PEOPLE THAT
WOULD DEAL WITH A CHUNK OF THE
SO-CALLED FISCAL CLIFF.
>> NOW, I TALKED TO A VARIETY
OF AIDES HERE ON CAPITOL HILL
ABOUT THAT IDEA OF THE PLAN B
OR SO.
THEY SAY THERE ARE LOTS OF
IDEAS FLOATING AROUND.
TONIGHT, OF COURSE, THE BIG
NEWS IS THAT THE PRESIDENT AND
THE SPEAKER OF THE HOUSE
MEETING FACE TO FACE IN THE
OVAL OFFICE AND WE WILL SEE AT
SOME POINT IF THERE IS
PROGRESS, HARRIS.
>> Harris: MIKE EMANUEL FROM
CAPITOL HILL, THANK YOU.
CONGRESS ALSO CONSIDERING A 60
BILLION-DOLLAR RELIEF PACKAGE
FOR VICTIMS OF SUPER STORM
SANDY.
AND NOW MORE THAN 125 LEADING
CEOS IN NEW YORK URGING
LAWMAKERS TO APPROVE THIS
THING.
AMONG THEM, TOP EXECUTIVES
FROM TIME WARNER, BLOOMBERG,
MORGAN STANLEY AND THE NBA.
JOINING GOVERNORS FROM NEW
YORK, NEW JERSEY, AND
CONNECTICUT ASKING CONGRESS TO
GET IT DONE BEFORE THEY BREAK
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
THEY SAY IT'S ALREADY TAKEN
CONGRESS TOO LONG TO ACT IN
THE AFTERMATH IN THE DISASTER.
PRESIDENT GEORGE H.W. BUSH
SHOULD BE ABLE TO CELEBRATE
CHRISTMAS AT HOME WITH HIS
FAMILY.
MR. BUSH, WHO IS 88 YEARS OLD,
HAS SPENT NEARLY THREE WEEKS
IN THE HOSPITAL IN TEXAS WHERE
DOCTORS HAVE BEEN TREATING HIM
FOR A COUGH RELATED TO
BRONCHITIS.
A HOSPITAL SPOKESPERSON SAYING
OUR NATION'S 41st PRESIDENT
IS IMPROVING AND DOCTORS DO
EXPECT HIM TO BE ABLE TO IT GO
HOME BY THE HOLIDAY.
THE SYRIAN GOVERNMENT'S
BIGGEST ALLY NOW ADMITTING THE
CIVIL WAR RAGING THERE MAY
WELL DOOM THE REGIME.
HEAR HOW U.S. OFFICIALS ARE
RESPONDING.
AND AS THE INVESTIGATION
CONTINUES INTO THE PLANE CRASH
THAT KILLED POP STAR JENNY
RIVERA THERE IS WORD TONIGHT
TWO POLICE OFFICERS ARE UNDER
ARREST FOR TAKING PICTURES OF
THE CRASH SITE AND STEALING
POTENTIAL EVIDENCE.
cer ]
YOU ARE A BUSINESS PRO.
GOVERNOR OF GETTING IT DONE.
YOU KNOW HOW TO DANCE...
WITH A DEADLINE.
AND YOU...RENT FROM NATIONAL.
BECAUSE ONLY NATIONAL LETS YOU
CHOOSE ANY CAR IN THE AISLE...
AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE A FULL-SIZE
OR ABOVE,
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
THIS IS AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS, BUSINESS PRO.
YES, IT IS.
GO NATIONAL. GO LIKE A PRO.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Sharable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>> Harris: THE SYRIAN
GOVERNMENT THAT HAS BEEN
SLAUGHTERING ITS OWN PEOPLE
FOR NEARLY TWO YEARS IS ON THE
BRINK OF COLLAPSE.
THAT FROM THE HEAD OF NATO.
HE HE SAYS IT'S ONLY A MATTER
OF TIME BEFORE BASHAR ASSAD IS
OUT OOF POWER.
ASSAD WANTS MOST POWERFUL ALLY
SEEMS TO BE LOSING HOPE.
TODAY A RUSSIAN OFFICIAL SAID
FOR THE FIRST TIME THE REBELS
MIGHT WIN THE CIVIL WAR.
AS HE PUT IT, WE HAVE
THE FACTS.
HE ALSO REVEALED MOSCOW IS
MAKING PLANS TO EVACUATE
THOUSANDS OF RUSSIAN CITIZENS
FROM SYRIA.
THE FALLOUT OF ASSAD WOULD
ALSO BE A HUGE BLOW TO HIS
OTHER ALLIES, IRAN AND THE
TERROR GROUP HEZBOLLAH.
"THE FOX REPORT'S"
CORRESPONDENT JONATHAN HUNT
LIVE IN OUR NEW YORK CITY
NEWSROOM NOW.
JONATHAN, THIS CHANGE OF TONE
FROM THE HUTIONS SEEMS TO BE
VERY SIGNIFICANT.
>> YEAH IT, CERTAINLY IS.
BECAUSE RUSSIA REMEMBER HAS
BEEN PRESIDENT BASHAR ASSAD'S
GREATEST ALLY AND PROTECTER.
IF THEY ARE CHANGING THEIR
TONE NOW, ACCEPTING THAT THE
REBELS ARE GETTING CLOSER AND
CLOSER TO ASSAD'S POWER CENTER
IN DAMASCUS THROUGH THE
VIOLENCE THAT WE HAVE SEEN
INTENSIFYING OVER THE LAST
COUPLE OF WEEKS, IT SIGNIFIES
THAT THE RUSSIANS ARE
REALIZING THAT THEIR GREATEST
FRIEND IN THE MIDDLE EAST IS
ABOUT TO BE OUT OF POWER AND
THEY BETTER PRETTY QUICKLY
START MAKING SOME NEW FRIENDS
AMONG THE REBEL OPPOSITION.
OFFICIALS SAY THEY ARE SIMPLY
PLEASED TO SEE THE RUSSIANS
FINALLY FACING UP TO REALITY,
LISTEN.
>> WE AGREE THAT ASSAD WILL
NOT BE A PART OF SYRIANS
FUTURE.
WE HAVE NOTED AS THE MEDIA HAS
THE PROGRESS THAT THE
OPPOSITION HAS BEEN MAKING.
WE STILL BELIEVE THAT FOR THE
SAKE OF THE SYRIAN PEOPLE
ASSAD OUGHT TO LEAVE NOW.
>> NOW THE QUESTIONS REMAIN OF
COURSE HOW LONG DOES PRESIDENT
ASSAD -- CAN PRESIDENT ASSAD
HOLD ON?
HOW DESPERATE DOES HE GET
WHILE HE DOES THAT AND IN THAT
DESPERATION, WHAT KIND OF
EXTREME MEASURES MIGHT HE
TAKE?
WHAT KIND OF WEAPONS MIGHT HE
USE AGAINST THE OPPOSITION AND
HIS OWN PEOPLE, HARRIS.
>> Harris: SYRIAN OFFICIALS
SEEM TO BE IN A STATE OF
DENIAL ABOUT ALL OF.
THIS CERTAINLY.
WE HAVEN'T HEARD FROM
PRESIDENT ASSAD HIMSELF.
BUT WE DID HEAR EXTENSIVELY
TODAY FROM HIS INFORMATION
MINISTER WHO TROTTED OUT SOME
WELL WARNED GOVERNMENT
CONSPIRACY THEORIES.
FOR INSTANCE, SAYING THAT THE
WESTERN ACCUSATIONS THAT THE
SYRIAN GOVERNMENT HAS USED
SCUD MISSILES IS JUST A LIE.
THAT THE TALK OF ASSAD'S DAYS
BEING NUMBERED IS AN ATTEMPT
BY THE INTERNATIONAL COMMUNITY
TO KIND OF CREATE A
SELF-FULFILLING PROPHECY.
HE ALSO TALKED ABOUT THE
RUSSIAN POSITION AND RATHER
CURIOUSLY SAID IT HASN'T
CHANGED AT ALL.
LISTEN.
>> I DON'T THINK THERE ANY
CHANGE IN THE RUSSIAN
POSITIONS.
THE ONLY THING THAT THE
AMERICAN POSITION CAME CLOSER
TO THE RUSSIAN POSITION.
FOR EXAMPLE, THE RUSSIANS HAVE
LISTED A TERRORIST GROUP, THAT
MEANS THE AMERICANS ARE COMING
CLOSER TO THE RUSSIAN'S SIDE.
I'M CONVINCED THERE IS NO
CHANGE IN --
>> WHETHER THAT WAS
INTENTIONALLY MISLEADING OR
NOT, IT CERTAINLY SEEMS
DIVORCE FROM REALITY TO
SUGGEST THAT THE U.S. POSITION
IS MOVING CLOSER TO THE
RUSSIANS.
RATHER THAN VISA VERSA.
REMEMBER, SADDAM HUSSEIN'S
INFORMATION MINISTER DURING
THE WAR IN IRAQ SEEMS WE MAY
HAVE ANOTHER BAGHDAD BUB ON
HER HANDS, HARRIS.
>> Harris: DIVORCE INDEED.
MAY IT WILL STARTED TO SINK IN
WITH THEY START PULLING OUT OF
THAT COUNTRY.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
IT IS NOT LOOKING SO GOOD FOR
THE MAN WHO CALLED A FORMER
AMERICAN PRESIDENT THE DEVIL.
VENEZUELAN PRESIDENT HUGO
CHAVEZ SUFFERED BLEEDING
DURING HIS CANCER SURGERY IN
CUBA ACCORDING TO THE
COUNTRY'S INFORMATION
MINISTER.
DOCTORED REPORTEDLY HAD TO
PERFORM CORRECTIVE MEASURES TO
STOP THE BLEEDING.
CHAVEZ JUST WON A SIX YEAR
TERM, BRAND NEW AS PRESIDENT.
IT'S APPEARING MORE UNLIKELY
THAT HE WILL ACTUALLY BE WELL
ENOUGH TO RETURN FROM CUBA IN
TIME FOR NEXT MONTH'S
INAUGURATION.
THE REMAINS OF THE SINGER AND
REALITY STAR JENNY RIVERA NOW
HEADED BACK HOME TO THE UNITED
STATES.
THAT'S ACCORDING TO GOVERNMENT
OFFICIALS IN MEXICO.
SHE DIED THERE ON SUNDAY WHEN
A LEHRER JET SHE CRASHED ON
CRASHED AFTER TAKING OFF IN
THE NORTHERN PART OF THE
COUNTRY.
RIVERA WAS ENORMOUSLY POPULAR
WITH MORE THAN 15 MILLION
ALBUMS SOLD.
ABC NEWS CONFIRMING SHE HAD
BEEN TALKING WITH THE NETWORK
ABOUT STARRING IN A SITCOM.
HER FAME APPARENTLY ATTRACTED
SOME SOUVENIR HUNTERS.
OFFICIALS SAY THEY HAVE
ARRESTED TWO POLICE OFFICERS
FOR STEALING ITEMS FROM THE
CRASH SITE.
EARLIER THIS WEEK A MEXICAN
TRANSPORTATION OFFICIAL SAID
RIVERA'S JET PLUNGED NEARLY
VERTICALLY FROM 28,000 FEET IN
THE AIR AND MAY HAVE HIT THE
GROUND AT MORE THAN 600 MILES
PER HOUR.
THE FAMILY OF A FORMER U.S.
MARINE SAYS HE IS STUCK IN A
PRISON INSIDE MEXICO ALL
BECAUSE OF AN HONEST MISTAKE.
THERE IS WORD NOW HIS LIFE
COULD BE IN DANGER.
RETURNING TO U.S. LAWMAKERS
FOR HELP.
PLUS, THE VERY UNUSUAL
CRIMINAL CASE INVOLVING
PRUNING SHEARS.
A PAISLEY TIE, AND AN APPARENT
PLOT TO KILL THIS GUY, THE
BEEBS.
POP STAR JUSTIN BEACH AS WE
APPROACH THE BOTTOM OF THE
HOUR.
TOP OF THE NEWS.
Playing sports is just
my whole life.
Looking back if it wasn't for
Shriners Hospital,
things would just be really,
really different.
I lost my leg when I was a kid.
There was a time when
I felt like I wasn't
going to be able to
walk again...
It was a pretty bad accident
But Shriners showed me who
I could be again.
They turned my whole
life around.
Hunter's life is one of nearly
a million changed
by donations from people
like you.
Send your love to the rescue.
Donate today.
And also to build my career.
So I'm not about to always let
my frequent bladder urges,
or the worry my pipes
might leak get in the way
of my busy lifestyle.
That's why I take care,
with VESIcare.
Once-daily VESIcare can help
control your bladder muscle
and is proven to treat
overactive bladder
with sympts of
frequent urges and leaks
day and night.
If you have certain stomach or
glaucoma problems,
or trouble emptying
your bladder,
do not take VESIcare.
VESIcare may cause allergic
reactions that may be serious.
If you experience swelling of
the face, lips,
throat or tongue,
stop taking VESIcare
and get emergency help.
Tell your doctor right away if
you have severe abdominal pain,
or become constipated for three
or more days.
VESIcare may
cause blurred vision,
so use caution while driving
or doing unsafe tasks.
Common side effects
are dry mouth, constipation,
and indigestion.
I've worked hard
to get to where I am...
and I've got better
aces to go
than always
going to the bathroom.
So take charge of your symptoms
by talking to your doctor
and go to vesicare.com
for a free trial offer.
>> Harris: TEENAGE SUPER STAR
JUSTIN BEACH THE TARGET OF AN
ALLEGED MURDER PLOT TO SAY THE
LEAST.
GROUP OF MEN PLAN TO KILL THE
BEEBS AS WELL AS BODY GUARD
AND TWO OTHERS ACCORDING TO
COURT DOCUMENTS THEY WERE
GOING TO STRANGLE AT LEAST TWO
OF THE VICTIMS WITH A PAISLEY
TIE AND CASTRATE THEM WITH
PRUNING SHEARS.
THAT'S THE ALLEGED MASTERMIND
THERE ON THE LEFT.
IS HE IN PRISON FOR RAPING AND
KILLING A 15-YEAR-OLD GIRL IN
VERMONT BACK IN 2000.
INVESTIGATORS SAY HE WAS
JUSTIN BEACH FAN AND HAS A
TATTOO OF THE TEENAGE STAR ON
HIS LEG.
WE ARE TOLD HE GOT UPSET WHEN
BEACH WOULD NOT RESPOND TO HIS
LETTERS AND DECIDED TO KILL
HIM.
THEN HE APPARENTLY GOT COLD
FEET AND CONFESS TO THE WHOLE
THING.
ALL THREE SUSPECTS FACING
CHARGES OF CONSPIRACY TO
COMMIT MURDER.
NEW YORK CITY POLICE SAY THEY
HAVE IDENTIFIED A SUSPECT IN
THAT BROAD DAYLIGHT EXECUTION
STYLE KILLING IN MIDTOWN
MANHATTAN, THAT'S ACCORDING TO
THE NAMES.
THE NEWSPAPER REPORTING
INVESTIGATORS ARE LOOKING FOR
A LOW LEVEL CRIMINAL FROM THE
BURROW OF QUEENS WHO MAY HAVE
DRIVEN A SILVER GET AWAY CAR
YOU SEE HERE.
FOX NEWS CANNOT CONFIRM THAT
ON MONDAY, A GUNMAN SHOT
ANOTHER MAN DEAD BEFORE HE
CALMLY GOT INTO THAT CAR WHICH
TURNED UP IN QUEENS.
THE SURVEILLANCE PICTURE SHOWS
THE VICTIM ON THE RIGHT.
THE SHOOTER ON THE LEFT ABOUT
TO PULL THE TRIGGER AS WE
UNDERSTAND.
IT ALL HAPPENED IN THE HEART
OF NEW YORK CITY JUST UPTOWN
FROM TIMES SQUARE.
THE VICTIM WAS FROM LOS
ANGELES AND HAD AN ARREST
RECORD REPORTS HE WORKED AT A
BANK AND MAY HAVE HAD TIES TO
THE MUSIC INDUSTRY.
>> THIS IS THE FOX REPORT.
A FORMER UNITED STATES MARINE
IS WASTING AWAY IN A MEXICAN
PRISON AT THIS HOUR AND
REPORTEDLY FACING THREATS
AGAINST HIS LIFE.
HIS NAME, JOHN HAMMER JR.
HE SERVED TOURS IN IRAQ AND
AFGHANISTAN SUFFERED FROM
POST-TRAUMATIC STRESS
DISORDER.
HE WAS HEADED TO MEXICO ON HIS
WAY TO A SURFING TRIP COSTA
RICA.
HAMMER TOLD U.S. BORDER
OFFICIALS IN TEXAS HE WANTED
TO TAKE WITH HIM HIS GREAT
GRANDFATHER'S ANTIQUE SHOTGUN.
OFFICIALS TOLD HIM NO PROBLEM.
LOCKED HIM UP ON JUDGE
CHARGES.
DON'T BRING YOUR GREAT
GRANDFATHER'S SHOTGUN INTO
MEXICO.
IF THAT'S AGAINST MEXICAN LAW
BUT THEY DIDN'T.
AND JOHN HAMMER EVER SINCE.
NEWS CONFERENCE LATER TOLD
SAID IT'S BEEN DIFFICULT BUT
HE IS HANGING IN THERE.
>> HE IS TOUGH.
A LESSER PERSON WOULD HAVE
PLEADED GUILTY BECAUSE THEY
HAVE BROUGHT HIM IN WITHOUT
COUNSEL TO THE COURTS HE SAID
I'M NOT DOING IT.
>> THAT MOM WENT ON TO CREDIT
THE MARINE CORPS WITH MAKING
HIM STRONG BUT HAMMER'S
PARENTS SAY THEY NEED THEIR
SON HOME NOW AND THEY ARE
APPEALING FOR ANY HELP THEY
CAN GET.
STEVE HARRIGAN IS LIVE IN OUR
SOUTHEAST NEWSROOM.
STEVE, HAMMER'S FATHER SAYS
PEOPLE HAVE THREATENED HIS
SON'S LIFE.
BOTH PARENTS SAY THEY HAVE
BEEN GETTING CALLS AT ALL
HOURS OF THE NIGHT FROM THAT
PRISON.
THE FIRST CALL DEMANDED $1,800
TO BE SENT BY WESTERN UNION OR
ELSE THEIR SON WOULD BE
KILLED.
HIS MOTHER SAID THIS WAS THE
ABSOLUTE WORSE MOMENT OF THIS
FOUR MONTH ORDEAL, HERE IS
WHAT SHE IS H. TO SAY.
>> IT WAS THE LONGEST NIGHT OF
MY LIFE, I WAS PHYSICALLY ILL
ALL NIGHT LONG JUST WAITING
FOR THE NEXT CALL AND THEY
WOULD CALL BACK AND TRYING TO
STALL THEM TO GIVE THE EMBASSY
TIME TO GET HIM ISOLATED.
>> AFTER THOSE ATTEMPTS AT
EXTORTION AND THREATS ON
HAMMER'S LIFE WERE MADE, HE
WAS MOVED FROM THE GENERAL
PRISON POPULATION INTO A
STORAGE ROOM, HARRIS.
FOUR MONTHS OF THIS AND NOW
REPORTS SURFACING THAT JAILERS
ARE CHAINING HIM TO HIS BED.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
WE SPOKE TO HIS LAWYER IN
MEXICO CITY THIS MORNING FOR A
TIME HAMMER WAS CHAINED TO HIS
BED BUT CURRENTLY NOT BEING
CHAINED THERE.
I ASKED HIS FATHER ABOUT THIS.
HIS FATHER VISITED THE PRISON
AND SAID WHILE HE WAS THERE
THAT JOHN HAMMER WAS IN FACT
CHAINED TO THE BED.
HERE IS WHAT THE FATHER HAD TO
SAY ABOUT THAT.
>> THEY CHAINED HIM TO THE BED
SO THAT THEY COULD FEEL SAFE
IS HE NOT GOING TO RUN AWAY
AND THEY ARE NOT GOING TO GET
IN TROUBLE.
>> CLEAR ON THE BORDER
ENTRANCE TO MEXICO.
SIGNS POSTED DO NOT BRING
FIREARMS INTO MEXICO BUT
HAMMER'S FAMILY CLAIMED THIS
60-YEAR-OLD RIFLE THAT
BELONGED TO HIS GREAT
GRANDFATHER THAT HAMMER
DECLARED IT ON BOTH SIDES OF
THE BORDER CUSTOMS AGENT BOTH
U.S. AND MEXICANS AND HE WAS
TOLD IT WOULD BE OKAY, HARRIS.
>> Harris: STEVE HARRIGAN
STAYING ON THE STORY TONIGHT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
SOFTWARE MOW JUGGLE JOHN
MCAFECES HE HAS BEEN ACTING
CRAZY ON PURPOSE.
HE ADMITS FAKING A HEART
ATTACK THAT SENT HIM TO THE
HOSPITAL LAST WEEK.
AS YOU MAY KNOW McAFEE
FOUNDED THE ANTIVIRUS PROGRAM
FOR COMMUTERS THAT BEARS HIS
NAME.
JOHN McAFEE ARRIVING IN THE
UNITED STATES LAST NIGHT AFTER
WEEKS OF TRYING TO ALLUDE
POLICE IN TWO DIFFERENT
COUNTRIES.
HIS TROUBLES BEGAN LAST MONTH
WHEN POLICE IN BELIZE TRIED TO
QUESTION HIM ABOUT HIS
NEIGHBOR'S HEARD.
HE SAYS HE HAD NOTHING TO DO
WITH IT AND ACCUSATIONS ARE
PART OF A GOVERNMENT PLOT.
THEN McAFEE WENT ON THE RUN.
ESCAPE NEXT DOOR TO GUATEMALA.
POLICE THERE CAUGHT HIM AND
ALL SET TO SEND HIM BACK TO
BELIZE WHEN HE DEVELOPED A
SUDDEN MEDICAL CONDITION
SENDING HIM BACK TO THE
HOSPITAL IN AN AMBULANCE.
WE ALL KNOW HE WAS FAKING.
STILL IT HELPED GOING BACK TO
BELIZE AND GUATEMALA ENDED UP
JUST SHIPPING McAFEE BACK TO
HIS HOME COUNTRY AMERICA.
TODAY HE HAD A SPECIAL MESSAGE
FOR EVERYBODY WHO HAS BEEN
FALLING HIS SAGA.
>> YOU PEOPLE AT HOME,
SERIOUSLY, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
YOU ARE LIVING YOUR LIVES.
YOU ARE LIVING YOUR LIVES
THROUGH OTHER PEOPLE.
RIGHT NOW THROUGH ME.
GET OFF THE SOFA AND TURN OFF
THIS TV SET.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Harris: THIS GUY LOVES A
NEWS CONFERENCE.
WELL, HE MADE IT ON TV AND NOW
QUESTION WHAT WILL HAPPEN TO
JOHN McAFEE NEXT.
PHIL KEATING LIVE IN MIAMI
BEACH.
ANY CHANCE THAT THE U.S. SENDS
HIM BACK TO BELIZE AT THIS
POINT?
>> HARRIS, THAT CHANCE
ABSOLUTELY STILL EXISTS BUT IT
DEPENDS ON THE POLICE IN BLEEZ
IF THEY CHANGE PERSON OF
INTEREST TO SOMEONE CRITICALLY
LIABLE IN THE SHOOTING DEATH
OF GREGORY, THE EXNEIGHBOR OF
McAFEE DOWN IN BELIZE WHO WAS
COMPLAINING OF HIS DOGS AND
THEN SHOT BY BULLETS IN HIS
APARTMENT DOWN THE STREET
FROM McAFEE.
THE COPS DOWN THERE WANTED TO
TALK TO McAFEE EVER SINCE
THIS HAPPENED IN EARLY
NOVEMBER.
HE WENT ON THE RUN BUT TODAY
HE INSISTS HE HE HAS NOTHING
TO HIDE.
>> I WANT TO MAKE THIS CLEAR
FOR THE 100TH TIME I HAVE
ABSOLUTELY NOTHING TO DO WITH
THE MURDER IN BELIZE.
THIS IS NOT ABOUT A MURDER IN
BELIZE.
>> SO AT THIS POINT THERE IS
ABSOLUTELY NO EXTRADITION
REQUEST FROM BELIZE.
IT HASN'T REACHED THAT POINT.
AND THE FBI TELLS US AT THIS
POINT IT HAS NO INVOLVEMENT
WITH THIS CASE.
HARRIS?
>> Harris: IS HE LIKE A
SELF-MADE CELEBRITY, THIS GUY.
I UNDERSTAND HE HAS FEW
MINUTES AGO.
LEFT HIS HOTEL BEHIND ME AND
NOW TAKING A STROLL NORTHBOUND
HERE GORGEOUS OCEAN DRIVE WITH
ALL THE ART DZEKO HOTELS.
EARLIER HE DID SOME SHOPPING
AND HE WAS CAUGHT BY A MIAMI
GERALDO PHOTOGRAPHER INK THERE
ON HIS BACK.
WHEN HE IS WALKING AROUND HE
IS NOT ONLY SURROUNDED BY
CAMERAS FROM NOT ONLY NATIONAL
BUT INTERNATIONAL AS WELL
TOURISTS USING PICTURES WITH
HIM.
McAFEE HE LIKES TO HEAR IN
SOUTH BEACH NO LONGER IN
CENTRAL AMERICAN JAIL.
>> I LIKE TO WALK AROUND.
I LIKE THE FACT THAT THERE IS
NO ONE TRYING TO SHOOT ME.
I'M VERY HAPPY BEING HERE.
>> 20-YEAR-OLD GIRLFRIEND
SAMANTHA AS DOES HIS OTHER
GIRLFRIEND 18-YEAR-OLD NAMED
AMY.
McAFECES THEY ARE IN HIDING
FOR HIS OWN SAFETY BUT HE IS
TRYING TO GET THE STATE
DEPARTMENT TO HELP GET HIM
HERE SOON LOVELY SOUTH BEACH.
HARRIS?
>> Harris: PEOPLE POSING FOR
PICTURES.
NO OFFICIAL CHARGES AGAINST
THIS GUY BUT THEY DO WANT TO
TALK TO HIM ABOUT HIS
NEIGHBOR'S MURDER.
>> YEAH.
WE WERE TALKING ABOUT THAT
WITH SOME OF THE TOURISTS.
HE IS A SUSPECT TO A DEGREE BY
POLICE IN BELIZE FOR A MURDER.
BUT STILL HE HAS BECOME SO
WIDELY KNOWN THANKS TO HIS
BLOGS AND NONSTOP TV COVERAGE
OR THE LAST SEVERAL WEEKS SET
LATEST SPECTACLE AS YOU SAID.
>> Harris: PHIL KEATING LIVE
IN MIAMI BEACH.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
CHILD SEX ABUSE ACCUSATIONS
AGAINST A MAJOR NONPROFIT
ORGANIZATION.
A DOCTOR NOW CLAIMING THAT THE
MAN WHO ULTIMATELY BECAME THE
CEO OF MOOSE INTERNATIONAL
MOLESTED HIM MORE THAN THREE
DECADES AGO.
THAT ORGANIZATION HAS SOME
1800 MOOSE LODGES ACROSS THE
U.S. AND OTHER COUNTRIES WHICH
IT SAYS ARE DEDICATED TO
COMMUNITY SERVICE.
NOW THE ACCUSER TELLING FOX
NEWS COVERAGE OF THE TRIAL OF
EXPENN STATE COACH JERRY
SANDUSKY MOTIVATED HIM TO COME
FORWARD.
JOHN ROBERTS IS LIVE FOR US IN
CHARLOTTE, NORTH CAROLINA.
JOHN?
>> ONLY 1800 LODGES ACROSS THE
COUNTRY.
CHILD CITY AND SCHOOL FOR
NEEDY CHILDREN ATTACHED TO
MOOSE INTERNATIONAL
HEADQUARTERS.
OFFICIALS TOLD ME LATE THIS
AFTERNOON THEY HAVE NOT BEEN
ABLE TO GET IN TOUCH.
NOR HAVE WE.
WE TRIED ALL DAY.
HE IS OUT OF THE COUNTRY
APPARENTLY ON A CRUISE WITH
HIS WIFE CELEBRATING THEIR
50TH WEDDING ANNIVERSARY IN
HIS ABSENCE MOOSE
INTERNATIONAL PROVIDED ME WITH
THIS STATEMENT THIS AFTERNOON
SAYING QUOTE THE MOOSE
FRATERNITY IS SHOCKED BY THIS
ALLEGATION AS THIS IS NOT THE K.
THE MOOSE ORGANIZATION IS NOT
A PARTY TO THIS LAWSUIT
CONSISTENT WITH BOARD LAWSUIT.
MR. AIREY WILL NOT BE IN
CONTACT WITH RESIDENTIAL
STUDENTS AT MOOSE HEART UNTIL
FURTHER NOTICE.
THE MAN WHO BROUGHT THIS SUIT
DR. JASON PECK TOLD ME IN AN
EXCLUSIVE INTERVIEW THAT HE
WAS BEFRIENDED BY AIREY AT THE
AGE OF 11 OR 12 WHEN THEY
LIVED IN COLUMBUS, OHIO.
THAT HE WOULD TAKE HIM TO MANY
MOOSE RELATED EVENTS SOME OF
THEM OVERNIGHT TRIPS THAT HIS
MOTHER ACTUALLY GAVE THE
BLESSING FOR IT WAS ON ONE OF
THOSE OVERNIGHT TRIPS IN OHIO
THAT PECK TOLD ME AIREY
ALLEGEDLY SEXUALLY ASSAULTED
HIM.
>> IT WAS IN THE MIDDLE OF THE
NIGHT.
THE ROOM WAS PITCH BLACK.
I WAS SHOCKED, VERY SCARED.
I RECALL TEARS COMING DOWN MY
FACE AND WETTING THE PILLOW
BEHIND ME AND I LAID PERFECTLY
STILL AND PRETTY MUCH JUST
KIND OF WENT INTO SHOCK MODE.
AND I DIDN'T KNOW IF I WAS
GOING TO BE HURT OR INJURED IF
I TRIED TO FIGHT BACK SO I
DIDN'T.
OF HOCKEY PLAYER THORN FLURRY
COMING FORWARD TO SAY THAT HE
HAD BEEN SEXUALLY ABUSED AS A
JUNIOR HOCKEY PLAYER HE
THOUGHT TO HIMSELF IF A TOUGH
GUY LIKE FLURRY WOULD COME
FORWARD SO COULD I.
HARRIS?
>> Harris: IT'S SAD THAT THERE
ARE SO MANY OF THESE STORIES
AND VICTIMS TO COME FORWARD.
JOHN ROBERTS, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
A HOLIDAY SURPRISE FOR MANY
APPLE FANS.
THE LONG AWAITED RETURN OF
GOOGLE MAPS AND WHAT IT MEANS
FOR iPHONE USERS WHERE TO GO
AND HOW TO GET THERE.
YOU
♪
AWW MAN.
[ Male Announcer ] RETURNS
ARE EASY WITH FREE PICKUP
FROM THE U.S. POSTAL SERVICE.
WE'LL EVEN DROP OFF BOXES
IF YOU NEED THEM.
VISIT USPS.COM
PAY, PRINT,
AND HAVE IT PICKED UP FOR FREE.
ANY TIME OF YEAR.
♪
NICE SWEATER.
THANK YOU.
♪
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAN
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
TO TELL REAL PEOPLE ABOUT
OUR NEW 15 UNDER $15 MENU.
OH MY GOODNESS!
OH MY GOSH,
THIS LOOKS AMAZING!
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR NEW MAINE STAYS!
15ENTREES UNDER $15,
SEAFOOD, CHICKEN AND MORE!
OOTHE TILAPIAWITH ROASTEDEGETAB!
I'M ACTUALLY LOOKING AT
THE WO GRILLED CHICKEN
WITH PORTOBELLO WINE SAUCE.
AT PORK CHOP
WAS GREAT!
NO MORE
FAST FOOD FRIDAY'S!
WE'RE GOING TO GO
TO RED LOBSTER.
YEP.
[ Male Announcer ]
COME TRY OUR NEW MENU
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
SALAD, SANDWICHES, AND MORE.
BY SHOWING YOU
THE APARTMENT BUILDING
WHERE THE FIRE WAS.
WHEN THINGS LIKE THIS HAPPEN,
I THINK YOU FIND
A NEW PERSPECTIVE ON LIFE.
RED CROSS PUT US IN A HOTEL
SO WE WERE ABLE
TO STAY TOGETHER.
WE'RE STRONG
AND IF WE OVERCAME THAT
OR IF WE CAN OVERCOME THAT...
WE CAN OVERCOME ANYTHING.
[ SNIFFLES ]
♪
>> Harris: iPHONE USERS WHO
I GUESS TEND TO GET LOST
GETTING SOME GOOD NEWS THE
GOOGLE MAPS APP. IS BACK AND
AVAILABLE FOR DOWNLOAD.
IN SEPTEMBER, IF YOU ARE AN
APPLE OWNER YOU KNOW APPLE
REPLACED GOOGLE MAPS WITH ITS
OWN BUILT-IN NAVIGATION SYSTEM
AND PEOPLE WERE COMPLAINING
BIG TIME.
APPLE'S VERSION MISPLACED LAND
MARKS, OVERLOOKED TOWNS AND
SOMETIMES GOT THEM COMPLETELY
LOST.
AUSTRALIAN POLICE SAYING APPLE
MAPS WERE 40 MILES LOST AND
LEFT USERS THERE DANGEROUSLY
STRANDED IN THE OUTBACK.
THINGS GOT SO BAD APPLE'S CEO
ISSUED A PUBLIC APOLOGY,
THAT'S NEVER GOOD AND
RECOMMENDED USE OTHER
COMPANY'S MAPS THROUGH WEB
BROWSERS.
STARTING TODAY APPLE LOYALISTS
ARE PUTTING FAITH IN THE
LITTLE BLUE DOT.
GOOGLE MAPS RANKED FIRST AMONG
ALL FREE DOWNLOADS IN THE APPS
STORE.
ADAM SHAPIRO JOINS ME NOW.
ADAM YOU WERE GIVING TUTORIAL.
YOURS STILL ISN'T WORKING.
>> THIS IS AN APPLE AND
IPHONE 5.
I PUT IN MY HOME ADDRESS THERE
IN NEW YORK CITY.
YOU SEE THAT RED DOT?
THAT'S MY HOME ADDRESS.
RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE OF CENTRAL
PARK.
>> YOU DON'T LIVE IN CENTRAL
>> FORTUNATELY I DON'T LIVE IN
THE MIDDLE OF CENTRAL PARK.
IT'S ABOUT 30 BLOCKS OFF.
IT'S NEVER FUNCTIONED
PROPERLY.
THE QUESTION IS WHY?
IS THE GOOGLE MAP REALLY THAT
MUCH BETTER?
IF YOU HAVE AN ANDROID PHONE
WITH A GOOGLE MAP SYSTEM IT
WORKED REALLY GREAT.
HAD YOU GREAT MAPPING.
NOW, WITH THE APPLE iPHONE
AND THE NEW GOOGLE APP. YOU
GET THE SAME MAPPING.
YOU GET GREAT MAPPING.
INVESTORS AND PEOPLE WHO USE
iPHONES ARE LOVING THE NEW
GOOGLE APPLICATION.
IT'S THE NUMBER ONE DOWNLOAD
FROM THE APPLE I STORE.
AND OF THE THOUSANDS UPON
THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE WHO HAVE
DOWNLOADED THE APPLICATION
BETWEEN LAST NIGHT AND TODAY
90% HAVE GIVEN IT A 5-STAR
RATING.
APPLE HAS JUST SCORED A
VICTORY.
THEY NOW HAVE AN EQUALLY GOOD
MAP AS THEIR COMPETITOR PHONE
ON ANDROID SYSTEM.
>> Harris: YOU SAID WE SHOULD
SMELL SOMETHING HERE?
>> THAT'S THE CONSPIRACY.
A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE THINKING
THIS IS A BLACK EYE FOR APPLE.
THIS IS A COMPANY THAT MAKES
TERRIFIC PRODUCTS.
HAS INCREDIBLY GOOD SOFTWARE
AND HAS A DUD OF A NO GOOD
APPLICATION IN THEIR OWN
MAPPING SYSTEM.
WHEN THEY DIVORCE THEMSELVES
FROM GOOGLE, GOOGLE WAS
COMPETING WITH THEM WITH THE
ANDROID PHONES AND THEY
WEREN'T GETTING AS GOOD OF A
MAP.
THEY NOW HAVE AS GOOD A MAP.
THE APPLE SHARE PRICE WENT
DOWN TODAY.
IT WAS OFF 2%.
GOOGLE SHARE PRICE WENT UP.
BUT YOU NOW HAVE AN iPHONE
THAT WILL COMPETE WITH A
SAMSUNG YOU KNOW GALAXY WITH
AN ANDROID OPERATING SYSTEM
AND HAVE EQUAL MAPPING
CAPABILITY.
THE iPHONE NOW HAS GOOD A
MAP SYSTEM THROUGH GOOGLE AS
THE ANDROID.
APPLE SCORES THAT WAY.
>> Harris: WOW, OKAY.
I WOULD IMAGINE INVESTORS ALL
AROUND PROBABLY HAPPY.
>> THEY WILL BE HAPPY.
THEY WILL START BUYING APPLE
SHARES AGAIN.
DISCOUNT DOWN 2% TODAY PERHAPS
FOR OTHER REASONS.
>> Harris: MOVE OUT OF CENTRAL
PARK.
>> YOU GOT IT.
>> Harris: UNEMPLOYMENT
APPLICATIONS DROPPING FOR THE
FOURTH STRAIGHT WEEK.
THE LABOR DEPARTMENT REPORTING
JOBLESS CLAIMS FELL TO 343,000
A TWO MONTH LOW IN THE SECOND
LOWEST LEVEL ALL YEAR.
IT'S A GOOD SIGN COMPANIES ARE
CUTTING FEWER JOBS.
THEY ALSO HAVE TO BEGIN HIRING
TO BRING DOWN THE UNEMPLOYMENT
RATE.
GAS PRICES FELL BIG TIME LAST
MONTH AT THE FASTEST RATE IN
MORE THAN THREE YEARS.
ANALYSTS SAY THAT'S HELPED
KEEP OVERALL INFLATION IN
CHECK PRICE AT THE PUMP STILL
GOING DOWN.
AVERAGE PRICE OF A GALLON OF
REGULAR UNLEADED 3.30 A DROP
14 CENTS SINCE LAST MONTH.
A TROPICAL I STORM TEARS
THROUGH DESTROYING LIVES.
TWO PEOPLE DEAD.
OUR TOP STORY AS WE GO AREND A
THE WORLD IN 80 SECONDS.
>> IS SAM SAMOA.
LOCAL MEDIA REPORT WIND GUSTS
130 MILES PER HOUR.
UPROOTED TREES AND DOWNED
POWER LINES BLOCKING ROADS AS
HEAVY RAIN AND HIGH SURF
POUNDED THE SOUTH PACIFIC
ISLAND.
SEVERAL HOMES REPORTEDLY
DAMAGED OR DESTROYED.
OFFICIALS DECLARING A SAFETY
DISASTER.
RUSSIA.
HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE FLOCK
TOWARD AN ERUPTING VOLCANO IN
THE FAR EAST.
SOME TOURISTS REPORTEDLY
PAYING UP TO A THOUSAND BUCKS
TO POSE IN FRONT OF MOLTEN
ROCKS AND BURNING TREES.
THE VOLCANO STARTED SPEWING
ASH AND LAVA LAST MONTH.
FIRST ERUPTION IN MORE THAN 40
YEARS.
PERU THE FULLY RECONSTRUCTED
FACE OF A PRIEST HOOD WHO
RULED SOME 800 YEARS AGO NOW
ON DISPLAY IN A MUSEUM IN THE
NORTHWEST.
ARCHAEOLOGISTS FOUND HER
REMAINS IN A TOMB LAST YEAR.
THEY USED OLD PHOTOGRAPHS OF
LOCAL WOMEN AND COMPUTER
GENERATED IMAGES FOR THE
RECONSTRUCTION.
SWEDEN, A 40-FOOT TALL STRAW
CHRISTMAS GHOST UP IN FLAMES
IN A TOWN SQUARE NORTH OF
STOCKHOLM.
PUTTING IT TOGETHER HAS BEEN A
HOLIDAY TRADITION SINCE 1966.
BUT APPARENTLY SO IS BURNING
IT OFFICIALS SAY SUSPECTED
ARSONISTS HAVE SET FIRE 39
TIMES THEY DID IT AFTER POLICE
HOSED IT DOWN HOURS EARLIER.
THAT'S A WRAP ON THIS FOX TRIP
AROUND THE WORLD IN 80
SECONDS:
>> Harris: THE LATEST EXPORT
FROM CHINA SEEMS TO BE COLLEGE
STUDENTS.
MORE AND MORE CHINESE SCHOLARS
ARE ATTEND ITING AMERICAN
INSTITUTIONS THESE DAYS.
SUPPORTERS SAY IT HELPS THE
UNIVERSITY PAY THEIR BILLS BUT
CRITICS ARGUE THIS TREND HAS A
DOWNSIDE.
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with uimited
talk and text.
by HTC for $49.99.
I HEARD YOU GUYS CAN SHIP GROUND
FOR LESS THAN THE UPS STORE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I'VE LEARNED THE ONLY WAY TO GET
A HOLIDAY DEAL IS TO CAMP OUT.
YOU KNOW WE'VE BEEN OPEN
ALL NIGHT.
IS THIS A TRICK
TO GET MY SPOT?
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SAVE ON GROUND SHIPPING
AT FEDEX OFFICE.
>> Harris: THE HOTTEST NEW
THING IN CHINA SEEMS TO BE THE
STUDENT, AND AT A TIME WHEN
STUDENT LOAN DEBT IS GREATER
THAN CREDIT CARD DEBT, SCHOOLS
ARE INCREASINGLY LOOKING
OVERSEAS FOR A BOOST.
ACCORDING TO A RECENT REPORT,
COLLEGE KIDS FROM CHINA NOW
MAKE UP A QUARTER OF ALL
INTERNATIONAL STUDENTS IN
AMERICAN UNIVERSITIES.
THE SCHOOLS CLAIM IT HELPS
WITH THEIR BOTTOM LINE AND
IMPROVES GRADUATION RATES.
SOME EVEN SENDING FACULTY
ABROAD TO ATTRACT POTENTIAL
STUDENTS TO COME HERE.
BUT SOME EXPERTS SAY MANY OF
THEM STRUGGLE WITH ENGLISH AND
TEACHERS WIND UP USING VALUE I
CAN'T BELIEVE CLASSROOM TIME
TO ACCOMMODATE THEM.
CLAUDIA COWAN WITH MORE LIVE
FROM OUR SAN FRANCISCO
NEWSROOM.
CLAUDIA?
>> HARRIS, THE SURGE IS BEING
DRIVEN IN LARGE PART BY THAT
COUNTRY'S BOOMING ECONOMY.
IT MEANS FOR THE FIRST TIME IN
CHINA'S HISTORY MILLIONS OF
FAMILIES CAN AFFORD TO SEND
THEIR CHILDREN TO AMERICAN
COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES.
BECAUSE THEY ARE WILLING TO
PAY FULL FREIGHT, OFTEN TENS
OF THOUSANDS OF DOLLARS IN
TUITION, CHINESE STUDENTS ARE
COVETED, INDEED MANY U.S.
COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES
TODAY ACTIVELY RECRUIT IN
CHINA.
WHILE THE INFLUX HAS LED TO
GREATER DIVERSITY ON CAMPUS IT
HAS ALSO BROUGHT CHALLENGES,
CHIEF AMONG THEM THE LANGUAGE
BARRIER.
CHINESE STUDENTS HAVE HAD
USE-TO-USE HEAD SETS FROM
ENGLISH TO MAN DARR WRITTEN
TRANSLATION.
ENROLLS HUNDREDS OF STUDENTS
CHINA ONE ADMINISTRATOR QUIT
OVER THAT SCHOOL'S AGGRESSIVE
RECRUITING POLICY.
MANY CAMPUSES SAY THEY ARE
TRYING TO STRIKE A BALANCE AS
THEY WORK TO ACCOMMODATE SOME
YOUNG PEOPLE COMING PRIMARILY
FROM ONE COUNTRY.
>> IF YOU GO INTO A BUSINESS
CLASS AND 80% OF THE STUDENTS
THERE ARE CHINESE, THAT'S NOT
WHAT THE CHINESE WANTED AND
THAT'S NOT WHAT THE 20% OF
AMERICANS WERE EXPECTING,
EITHER.
>> EVEN SO, MANY U.S. COLLEGES
ARE STEPPING UP THEIR
RECRUITING EFFORTS.
SOME ARE EVEN HAVING THEIR
PROFESSORS LEARN ABOUT CHINESE
CULTURE AND TRADITIONS TO HELP
THESE STUDENTS BETTER ENGAGE
IN CLASS.
HARRIS?
>> Harris: CLAUDIA, THANK YOU.
THE OLYMPIC RUNNER WITH NO
LEGS STUNNED FANS THIS PAST
SUMMER IN LONDON.
ENOUGH TO HE HAS HIT THE TRACK
AGAINST A NEW KIND OF
COMPETITION BLADE RUNNER GOING
HEAD TO HEAD WITH A HORSE.
WE'LL SHOW YOU WHO WON THE
RACE.
FIRST, THE MAN WHO HELPED
CREATE THE BAR CODE WHICH
APPEARS ON NEARLY EVERYTHING
WE BUY HAS DIED.
NORMAN JOSEPH WOODLAND WORKED
ON THE MANHATTAN PROJECT THE
U.S. MILITARY'S ATOMIC BOMB
DEVELOPMENT TEAM.
HE LATER DROPPED OUT OOF
GRADUATE SCHOOL TO DEVELOP THE
BAR CODE.
LATER 67-CENT PACKAGE OF
WRIGGLY'S CHEWING GAME WAS THE
FIRST TO SELL WITH THE PBC.
5 BILLION PRODUCTS ARE SCANNED
AND TRACED AND TRACKED
WORLDWIDE EVERY DAY.
NORMAN JOSEPH WOODLAND DEAD
TODAY AT 91.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] CAMPBELL'S
GREEN BEAN CASSEROLE.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO
IS EFFICIENTLY ABSORBED IN SMALL
CONTINUOUS AMOUNTS.
Citracal Slow Release
CONTINUOUSLY RELEASES CALCIUM
PLUS D
WITH EFFICIENT ABSORPTION
IN ONE DAILY DOSE.
Citracal Slow Release.
WITMeet the 5-passengerON
IFord C-MAX Hybrid.
When you're carrying
a lot of weight,
C-MAX has a nice little trait,
You see, C-MAX helps
you load your freight,
with its foot-activated
lift gate.
But that's not
all you'll see,
Cause C-MAX also
beats Prius v,
with better MPG.
Say hi to the all-new 47
combined MPG C-MAX Hybrid.
BUT WE CAN STILL HELP YOU SEE
YOUR BIG PICTURE.
WITH THE FIDELITY
GUIDED PORTFOLIO SUMMARY,
YOU CHOOSE
WHICH ACCOUNTS TO TRACK
AND USE FIDELITY'S ANALYTICS
TO SPOT TRENDS,
GAIN INSIGHTS, AND FIGURE OUT
WHAT YOU WANT TO DO NEXT.
ALL IN ONE PLACE.
I'M MEREDITH STODDARD
AND I HELPED CREATE
THE FIDELITY GUIDED
PORTFOLIO SUMMARY.
IT'S ONE MORE INNOVATIVE REASON
SERIOUS INVESTORS
ARE CHOOSING FIDELITY.
NOW GET 200 FREE TRADES
WHEN YOU OPEN AN ACCOUNT.
OTHERS WITH DISABILITY.
>> IT WASN'T ABOUT WHO WON
TODAY.
IT WAS ABOUT COMING OUT HERE
AND REALLY JUST SHOWING PEOPLE
DISABILITIES, YOU KNOW,.
>> Harris: ALL RIGHT AGAIN HE
WON.
TO BE FAIR BUSINESS TOROUS
PRIX STOROUS.
SINCE HE WAS STALLION FEW
WOULD CLAIM HE HAD ADVANTAGE
IN THE END.
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND JOHN
BOEHNER MEETING FACE TO FACE
FOR THE SECOND TIME THIS WEEK
TO WORK ON A DEAL TO AVOID THE
SO-CALLED FISCAL CLIFF.
AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE
WITHDRAWING HERSELF FROM
CONSIDERATION TO REPLACE
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON.
WHAT SHE CALLS A VERY
POLITICIZED CONFIRMATION
PROCESS.
ON THIS DAY IN 1636 A COURT
FORMALLY RECOGNIZED THE
MILITARY ORGANIZATION THAT
WOULD BECOME THE NATIONAL
GUARD.
THE GENERAL COURT OF THE
MASSACHUSETTS BAY CLONE
ORDERED THE CLONE'S MILITIA
INTO THREE REGIMENTS.
ALSO ESTABLISHED THAT ALL ABLE
BODIED MEN BETWEEN THE AGES O