JON: IT'S JUST BEEN AN AWFUL
MORNING.
IT STARTED OUT WITH THE EARLY
REPORTS OF A SHOOTING, AND WE
JUST DID NOT KNOW HOW BAD THIS
WAS BUT, AGAIN, THE INDICATIONS
ARE THAT 26 PEOPLE ARE DEAD, 18
OF THEM CHILDREN.
THE GUNMAN WE DO KNOW IS DEAD,
ALTHOUGH THERE IS TALK OF
POTENTIALLY A SECOND GUNMAN THAT
POLICE ARE STILL LOOKING FOR.
WE ARE AWAITING THAT NEWS
CONFERENCE AND PERHAPS WE'LL GET
SOME OF THOSE ANSWERS THEN.
JENNA: CONTINUING COVERAGE NOW
ON "AMERICA LIVE."
MEGYN: FOX NEWS ALERT ON A
DEVELOPING SITUATION, AND THERE
IS DEVASTATION AT THIS HOUR IN
CONNECTICUT AS WE AWAIT A POLICE
NEWS CONFERENCE ON A DEADLY
SHOOTING AT A CONNECTICUT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AT A CONNECTICUT ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
SOURCES ARE TELLING FOX NEWS THE
26 PEOPLE ARE DEAD AT THIS TIME.
EIGHT ADULTS, INCLUDING THE
SHOOTER, AND 18 CHILDREN.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US ON
THIS IMPORTANT AFTERNOON AT
"AMERICA LIVE."
I AM MEGYN KELLY.
LOOKING LIVE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AT NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
BREAKING CHILDREN BEING LED
ACROSS A PARKING LOT.
AN EXPRESSION OF TERROR BEEN
ACROSS THE FACE OF THAT ONE
LITTLE GIRL IN THE BLUE SHIRT.
THE MOTHER OF THE CHILD CALLED
IN TO FOX NEWS.
JENNA: CAN YOU TELL US WHAT
HAPPENED INSIDE THE SCHOOL WERE
YOUR DAUGHTER WAS?
>> SHE WAS IN A SMALL CLASS, A
READING GROUP.
THEY STARTED HEARING BANGS AND
HER TEACHER, WHICH I AM SO
GRATEFUL FOR, THERE WAS JUST A
SMALL GROUP.
THEY RUSHED THE KIDS INTO THE
BATHROOM.
THEY LOCKED THE DOOR.
THEY JUST TOLD THE CHILDREN THAT
IT WAS HAMMERING, AND THEY TRIED
TO KEEP THEM CALM.
THE NEXT THING THAT I KNOW,
BECAUSE IT'S VERY HARD TO GET A
COMPLETE STORY, THE NEXT THING I
KNOW IS THAT THE POLICE CAME AND
THEY WERE KNOCKING ON THE DOOR
TO BE LET OUT OF THE CLASSROOM.
WHEN THEY WERE, THEY STOP
LAUGHING BLOOD.
ONE CHILD WAS COVERED IN BLOOD.
I UNDERSTAND THAT CHILD IS SAFE
AND WAS NOT HURT.
IT MUST HAVE BEEN SOMEBODY ELSE.
MEGYN: THERE IS A LOT OF
INFORMATION COMING INTO THE
NEWSROOM AT THIS HOUR.
THE NEWS HAS EVOLVED AS WE HAVE
LEARNED MORE INFORMATION.
I WOULD LIKE TO TELL THE VIEWERS
THAT WE ARE STILL AWAITING A THE
FIRST NEWS CONFERENCE ON THIS
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT.
THAT WILL HAPPEN ANY MOMENT NOW.
IT HAS BEEN SCHEDULED FOR
1:00 P.M. EASTERN TIME.
IT HAS BEEN PUSHED BACK SHORTLY
AS THEY GET THE OFFICIALS IN
PLACE.
THIS EVEN NEWS ORGANIZATIONS
WORKING TO GET THE MICROPHONES
SET UP.
WE ARE TOLD IT WILL HAPPEN
MOMENTARILY.
GOING LIVE TO TRACE GALLAGHER AT
THE NEWS DESK.
REPORTER: WE WANTED TO PLAY THIS
THING CAREFULLY.
WE HAVE BEEN GETTING THE NUMBERS
ALL MORNING LONG.
POLICE WERE HOLDING THIS VERY
CLOSE TO THE VEST.
WE HAVE NOW CONFIRMED WITH THE
JUSTICE DEPARTMENT THAT THE
NUMBERS ARE HORRIFYING.
TWENTY-SEVEN DEAD, INCLUDING 18
CHILDREN.
EIGHT ADULTS, AND THE GUNMEN.
IT ALL BEGINS TO MAKE SENSE.
BECAUSE EVEN IN THE EARLY GOING,
THE MAYOR AND THE POLICE
OFFICERS WERE SAYING THAT THIS
COULD BE FROM THE EARLY
ASSESSMENTS, ONE OF THE WORST
SHOOTINGS IN CONNECTICUT
HISTORY.
NOW WE KNOW IF THE NUMBERS HOLD
UP, THIS WOULD BE THE WORST
SHOOTING IN CONNECTICUT HISTORY.
THE GUNMAN, APPARENTLY, WAS IN
FULL CAMOUFLAGE.
HE WAS CARRYING TWO DIFFERENT
GUNS.
WE HEARD THROUGHOUT THE MORNING
WITH SOME OF THE WITNESSES HEARD
UP TO 100 SHOTS BEING FIRED.
NOW YOU HAVE THESE NUMBERS.
EARLIER THERE WAS A REPORT, AND
THIS APPARENTLY HAPPENED IN THE
KINDERGARTEN CLASS.
THE KINDERGARTEN CLASS WAS SO
FAR UNACCOUNTED FOR.
WE SAW PICTURES OF STUDENTS
BEING CARRIED AND SHEPHERDED OUT
OF THE SCHOOL TOWARD THE FIRE
STATION.
SOME OF THE AUTHORITIES AND
TEACHERS TELLING THE STUDENTS TO
PUT THEIR HEAD DOWN AND WENT TO
THE FIRE STATION AND DO NOT STOP
RUNNING UNTIL YOU GET THERE.
WE HEARD EARLY ON THAT THIS MAY
HAVE BEEN ISOLATED TO JUST BE
OFFICE.
THE GUNMAN MAY HAVE GONE IN THE
SCHOOL, WENT TO THE OFFICE, AND
OPENED FIRE ON A PRINCIPLE.
WE KNOW THAT THE VICE PRINCIPAL
WAS INJURED AND WE KNOW THAT
EIGHT ADULTS WITH SOME OF THEM
CLEARLY WERE IN.
THEY WERE IN THE PRINCIPAL'S
OFFICE.
THE PRINCIPAL, VICE PRINCIPAL
AND OTHERS, MOSTLY FEMALE
MEMBERS OF THE STAFF.
WE DO NOT YET KNOW THE BREAKDOWN
OF THE KINDERGARTEN CLASS.
KEEP IN MIND, THE SCHOOL IS IN
FAIRFIELD COUNTY.
A VERY UPSCALE COMMUNITY.
ALL SCHOOLS IN FAIRFIELD COUNTY,
I WOULD KNOW BECAUSE MY CHILDREN
WENT THERE AT ONE TIME, IT WOULD
BE LOCKED DOWN AT 9:30 A.M.
TO GET INTO THE SCHOOL, YOU HAVE
TO HAVE VISUAL IDENTIFICATION.
THERE ARE CAMERAS OUT FRONT AS
WELL AS
BEFORE THEY BUZZY WHEN COMING UP
TO LET THEM KNOW WHO YOU ARE.
THE SHOOTING REPORTEDLY HAPPENED
10 MINUTES AFTER THE DOORS WERE
LOCKED.
IT IS UNCLEAR IF THE GUNMAN CAME
IN BEFORE OR AFTER THAT.
BUT DURING THE MORNING
ANNOUNCEMENTS, WE ARE TOLD THAT
IS ONE THEY HEARD THE SHOTS
BEING FIRED.
AGAIN, UP TO 100 SHOTS.
NOW THEY ARE IN THE PROCESS OF
TRYING TO NOTIFY FAMILIES.
POLICE HAVE NOT COME OUT AND
SAID A SINGLE PUBLIC WORD ABOUT
THE NUMBER.
THIS IS ALL COMING FROM SOURCES.
OUR SOURCE HAPPENS TO BE THE
JUSTICE DEPARTMENT GIVING US THE
NUMBERS OF 27 DEAD, INCLUDING 18
CHILDREN.
AGAIN, NOT TO PANIC.
ANY PARENTS WHO HAVE CHILDREN IN
THE SCHOOL DISTRICT, WE DO NOT
KNOW YET WHERE THOSE CHILDREN
ARE LOCATED IN THE SCHOOL.
AS WE GET MORE BREAKING NEWS,
AND THERE IS MORE TO BE GONE, WE
WILL BRING IT TO YOU THROUGHOUT
THE BROADCAST.
MEGYN: THE HOSPITAL IN DANDER,
CONNECTICUT IS ON LOCKDOWN.
TO PROTECT THE CONFIDENTIALITY
OF THE PATIENTS, THEY SAY THEY
HAVE ONLY TREATED THREE PATIENTS
AND DON'T ANTICIPATE ANY MORE
BEING SENT TO THE HOSPITAL AT
THIS TIME.
THE HORRIFYING REALITY AT THIS
HOUR REMINDS ME OF WHAT HAPPENED
IN NEW YORK CITY AFTER 9/11,
WHEN THEY LINED UP OUTSIDE OF
THE HOSPITAL.
REPORTER: YOU COULD EVEN GO BACK
TO WHAT HAPPENED AT COLUMBINE.
OR PERHAPS AT GEORGIA TECH.
YOU CAN SEE AT ONE POINT IN
TIME, THEY WERE ALLUDING TO A
TRIAGE, WHICH IS A STANDING
OPERATING PROCEDURE AND THEY SET
UP A RED TARP AND A YELLOW TARP
AND OTHER TARPS AND THEY WILL
BRING THE PATIENTS OUT AND THEY
WILL ASSESS THEM AS THE NEED.
THE RED IS THE MOST SERIOUS.
THE YELLOW IS NOT SO SERIOUS,
AND THEN YOU MOVE ON DOWN THE
LINE.
WE LOOK AT THAT TREE ARE SET UP
AND THERE WASN'T A SINGLE
PATIENT OUT THERE.
AT FIRST, IT SEEMED TO BE A GOOD
SIGN.
NOW, AS YOU GO LATER ON AND YOU
SEE GOING BACK TO COLUMBINE AND
VIRGINIA TECH, BUT THAT
APPARENTLY WAS NOT A GOOD SIGN.
THE FATALITIES WERE APPARENTLY
IN THE OFFICE AND IN A CERTAIN
CLASSROOM, BUT WE THOUGH WE
DON'T KNOW WHICH CLASSROOM THEY
WERE IN.
YOU KIND OF TOUCHED ON HOW THE
WHOLE TOWN, ALL THE SCHOOLS ON
LOCKDOWN, THERE WAS A REPORT
EARLIER THAT POLICE HAD
SURROUNDED A PURPLE VAN THAT WAS
IN DANDER, WHICH IS JUST A FEW
MILES AWAY.
POLICE HAD ACTUALLY SURROUNDED
THAT BAN, MAYBE OUR PRECAUTION,
MAYBE SOMEONE ELSE INVOLVED.
WE ARE STILL WAITING TO GET THAT
INFORMATION FROM THE AUTHORITIES
MEGYN: STANDBY, WE ARE GOING
LIVE TO RICK LEVENTHAL WHO IS
NEAR THE SCHOOL AT A PARK WHERE
THE POLICE WILL BE HOLDING A
PRESS CONFERENCE.
REPORTER: WE ARE AT A PARK THAT
IS VERY CLOSE TO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
THE POLICE HAVE NOT ARRIVED YET
FOR THE NEWS CONFERENCE, BUT WE
HOPE TO HAVE A LOT MORE OF THESE
QUESTIONS ANSWERED WHEN THEY DO.
I HAVE HEARD FROM A FEDERAL
SOURCE PERSONALLY THAT THE
NUMBER DEAD WITH 26 OR 27, AND
INCLUDED 18 CHILDREN, ALSO
INCLUDED THE PRINCIPAL OF THE
SCHOOL AND THE GUNMAN.
TWO GUNMEN WERE AT THE SCENE.
A GLOCK PISTOL AND A NONMETAL --
9-MILLIMETER GUN.
HE WAS DRESSED IN CAMOUFLAGE.
POLICE ARE SAYING THAT HE -- BUT
THERE ISN'T AN ACTIVE SEARCH FOR
ANY MORE SHOOTERS AT THIS TIME.
THERE ARE SECURITY PROCEDURES IN
PLACE FOR THE DOOR SHOULD HAVE
BEEN LOCKED.
ANYONE WHO WANTED TO ENTER THE
SCHOOL AFTER 9:30 P.M. WOULD'VE
HAD TO BE BUZZED IN AND WOULD'VE
HAD TO SIGN IN WHEN THEY GOT
INTO THE SCHOOL ITSELF.
SO WE DO NOT KNOW HOW HE GOT IN,
BUT WE ARE TOLD THAT THIS GUNMAN
MAY HAVE KILLED AS MANY AS 26
PEOPLE IN THE SCHOOL, INCLUDING
UP TO 18 CHILDREN.
MEGYN: WHAT IS THE STATUS OF THE
CHILDREN?
WHAT IS THE STATUS OF THE
CHILDREN AT THIS HOUR?
>> WE WERE TOLD THAT SOME
PARENTS WERE REUNITED WITH THEIR
CHILDREN.
THE CHILDREN WILL BE --
MEGYN: STANDBY, WE HAVE A PARENT
ON CAMERA NOW.
>> IT STARTED WITH THE NEIGHBORS
AND SO IT IS -- [INAUDIBLE]
>> [INAUDIBLE QUESTION]
>> WHEN IT HAPPENED, YOU COULD
HEAR THE GUNSHOTS.
SO IT WAS VERY UPSETTING AND IT
IS ONE OF THOSE THINGS WHERE WE
ARE TRYING TO UNDERSTAND WHAT IS
HAPPENING.
IT IS GOING TO MAKE IT MUCH
WORSE.
>> [INAUDIBLE QUESTION]
>> I DO NOT KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
OUTSIDE OF THAT.
I DO NOT HAVE ANY INFORMATION
OTHER THAN WHAT PEOPLE ARE
SPECULATING.
MEGYN: THAT APPEARED TO BE ONE
OF THE PARENTS WHO HAVE OLDER
CHILDREN IN THE SCHOOL.
THE CHILDREN APPEARED TO HAVE
ESCAPED UNHARMED.
I WOULD LIKE TO GET BACK TO RICK
LEVENTHAL NOW.
HEARING FROM ONE OF THE PARENTS,
WHERE ARE THE CHILDREN?
WHEN THEY ARRIVED AT THE SCHOOL,
THEY WERE TOLD NOT TO ARRIVE.
BUT MANY PEOPLE CAME.
WHERE ARE THEY?
>> THEY HAVE SET UP AN AREA OF
THE LOCAL FIREHOUSE.
AS WE UNDERSTAND, MANY WERE LED
OUT OF THE SCHOOL.
THE TEACHERS LOCKED THEIR DOORS
WHEN THEY HEARD THE GUNSHOTS
FIRED.
MINUTES AGO, WE COULD SEE A LOT
OF POLICE OFFICERS BLOCKING ALL
THE ROADS THAT LEAD WHERE THE
SCHOOL IS LOCATED.
THAT ENTIRE AREA HAS BEEN
LOCKED.
SO THE POLICE HAVE THE AREA ON
LOCKDOWN.
WE KNOW THAT THEY HAVE THE
SCHOOL ON LOCKDOWN.
WE KNOW THAT THEY DID A ROOM BY
ROOM, SEARCH.
THEY LOCATED THE GUNMAN AND THE
CHILDREN.
AND AS FAR AS WE KNOW, CHILDREN
HAVE NOW BEEN REUNITED WITH
THEIR FAMILIES.
MEGYN: IS THERE ANY INFORMATION
ON THIS MAN'S CONNECTION TO THE
SCHOOL?
THE SHOOTER.
WE HEARD THAT THIS MAY HAVE BEEN
THE FATHER OF A STUDENT.
HAVE WE HEARD ANYTHING FROM ONE
PERSON ABOUT THAT?
>> I HAVE NOT HEARD THAT FROM
LAW ENFORCEMENT YET.
WE DO HAVE ONE SOURCE SUGGESTING
THE SHOOTER MAY HAVE BEEN A
YOUNG MAN, HIS YOUNG AT 20 YEARS
OLD.
WE ALSO HAVE HEARD THAT HE MAY
LIVE IN NEW JERSEY AND THERE MAY
HAVE BEEN A SEPARATE SITUATION
THERE.
A CRIME SCENE WHERE THEY KICKED
DOWN THE DOOR OF THE PERSON'S
HOME.
WE ARE TRYING TO CONFIRM THAT AT
THIS HOUR.
WE DON'T KNOW IF THAT IS TRUE AT
THIS HOUR SPUME WE ARE HEARING
THAT THERE ARE SWAT TEAMS AT
THIS PERSONS HOME, THE POSSIBLE
SHOOTER'S HOME.
WE CANNOT CONFIRM THAT YET THE
ONE I WOULD LIKE TO ASK YOU WHAT
THE STATUS IS AT THE SCHOOL AT
THIS HOUR.
THEY ARE NOT EXPECTING ANY MORE
VICTIMS TO BE BROUGHT TO THE
CONNECTICUT HOSPITAL IN DANBURY.
TWENTY-SIX DEAD CONFIRMED BY FOX
NEWS.
WE BELIEVE IT IS 26 PEOPLE PLUS
THE GUNMAN?
WE ARE GETTING DIFFERENT REPORTS
FOR THE QUESTION IS, DO WE
BELIEVE THAT THE VICTIMS ARE
STILL IN SCHOOL.
REPORTER: IF YOU HAVE THAT MANY
VICTIMS LOCATED IN THE SCHOOL,
IT IS GOING TO BE A VERY LONG
AND VERY DIFFICULT AND VERY
GRISLY CRIME SCENE IT HAS TO BE
PROCESSED BEFORE ANYBODY IS OUR
MOVE.
HAS TO BE CAREFULLY DOCUMENTED,
PHOTOGRAPHS HAVE TO BE TAKEN.
ALL VICTIMS HAVE TO BE SECURED.
THEN TRANSPORTED FROM THE SCENE
ONCE THE ENTIRE CRIME SCENE HAS
BEEN MAPPED OUT.
THAT COULD TAKE HOURS.
YOU CAN EXPECT A CRIME SEEN
AROUND THE SCHOOL FOR DAYS.
POLICE WILL CONTINUE TO KEEP
EVERYONE OUT AS THEY PROCESS
THIS END ARE COVERED THE VICTIMS
INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
IT WILL NOT BE OVER QUICKLY.
MEGYN: ONE CAN ONLY WONDER WHAT
THE PARENTS OF THOSE WHO ARE NOT
ACCOUNTED FOR ARE GOING THROUGH.
IS THERE A HOLDING PLACE FOR
THEM?
DO WE KNOW WHETHER THEY ARE
PRESENT ON THE SCENE AT ALL?
WE HAVEN'T SEEN THAT AS OF LATE.
REPORTER: OUR UNDERSTANDING IS
THAT EVERYONE WHO IS RUSHING
TOWARDS SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
WAS BEING STOPPED AND REDIRECTED
TO THE FIREHOUSE, POSSIBLY TO
OTHER LOCATIONS AT THIS POINT.
OUR UNDERSTANDING IS THAT THERE
ARE NO PARENTS NOW HAVE THE
SCHOOL ITSELF.
EVERYONE HAS BEEN MOVED AWAY SO
THAT THE POLICE CAN DO THEIR JOB
NOW PROCESSING THE SCENE.
ANY PARENT WHO MAY HAVE CHILDREN
WHO WERE TAKEN FROM THE SCHOOL,
AT THIS POINT SHOULD HAVE BEEN
REUNITED WITH THOSE CHILDREN.
WE IMAGINE THIS WILL BE A
DIFFICULT DAY FOR EVERYONE
INVOLVED.
MEGYN: THERE WERE REPORTS
EARLIER THAT WERE TOUCHED ON OF
A POSSIBLE ACCOMPLICE.
AND THERE WAS SOME TAPE OF
POLICE.
THESE ARE THE LUCKY ONES, THE
PARENTS WHO GET TO TAKE THEIR
KIDS ON TODAY AND EXPLAIN TO
THEM WHY 18 OF THEIR CLASSMATES
ARE DEAD.
THERE WERE REPORTS OF A SECOND
PERSON, PERHAPS AN ACCOMPLICE.
WE DIDN'T HEAR MUCH MORE ABOUT
THAT.
NOW WE ARE GETTING MORE REPORTS
FROM OTHER SOURCES FOR THAT A
SECOND PERSON MAY BE IN CUSTODY.
HAVE THEY SAID WHETHER THEY
BELIEVE THAT PIECE OF THE
INVESTIGATION IS STILL OPEN?
>> WHAT WE HAD HEARD IS THAT
THERE WAS A POTENTIAL SECOND
SUSPECT.
OFTENTIMES AFTER THESE MAJOR
INCIDENTS, YOU HAVE A LOT OF
REPORTS THAT TURN OUT TO BE
FALSE.
A LOT OF TIMES THERE IS
CONFUSION IN THE MIDST OF THINGS
AND SOMEONE COULD BE RUNNING
FROM THE SCENE.
SOMEONE WHO MAY BE ESCAPING WITH
THEIR LIFE.
PEOPLE COULD THINK THAT THEY ARE
FLEEING THE SCENE BECAUSE THEY
ARE INVOLVED.
WE DON'T KNOW.
WE ARE WAITING FOR POLICE TO
BRIEF US AND WE HAVE BEEN TOLD
THERE'S NO ACTIVE INVESTIGATION
OR SEARCH FOR A SECOND SHOOTER.
THAT COULD MEAN THE THEY HAVE
PARTY CAPTURED A SECOND PERSON
IF SOMEONE WAS INVOLVED.
BUT WE HAVEN'T CONFIRMED THAT
YET.
MEGYN: WE WOULD LIKE TO TELL OUR
VIEWERS THAT PRESIDENT OBAMA WAS
NOTIFIED OF THE SHOOTING AT 1030
EASTERN TIME.
THE FBI AND LOCAL ENFORCEMENT ON
SCENE.
HE WAS ASKED FOR HIS REACTION
AND JAY CARNEY SAID THAT HE DOES
NOT WANT TO RELAY THAT UNTIL WE
KNOW MORE ABOUT WHAT HAS
HAPPENED.
HONESTLY, THE PRESIDENT HAS A
FATHER, SO HE FEELS ENORMOUS
SYMPATHY FOR THE FAMILY AND
WANTS TO DO EVERYTHING THAT HE
CAN TO SUPPORT STATE AND LOCAL
LAW ENFORCEMENT DURING THIS
TRAGIC EVENT.
JAY CARNEY WAS SPECIFICALLY
ASKED ABOUT WHETHER ASSAULT
WEAPONS BANS, WHETHER THAT
REMAINS THE COMMITMENT OF THE
PRESIDENT.
AND THE ANSWER WAS YES, IT DOES
REMAIN A COMMITMENT OF HIS.
BUT TODAY IS NOT A DAY TO ENGAGE
IN THIS KIND OF DEBATE.
REPORTER: WE JUST GOT WORD THAT
AN ENTIRE ENTIRE CLASSROOM OF
STUDENTS WAS NOT ACCOUNTED
FOR.
WE WERE TOLD THAT YOU ARE IN
CLASS -- WOULD SUGGEST THAT AN
ENTIRE KINDERGARTEN CLASS WAS
GUNNED DOWN IN THIS HORRIBLE
INCIDENT.
MEGYN: RICK LEVENTHAL, WE WILL
COME BACK TO YOU IN A MOMENT.
THE REPORTING SEEMS TO BE COMING
TOGETHER FROM MULTIPLE SOURCES.
TWENTY-SIX PEOPLE DEAD,
INCLUDING 18 CHILDREN.
AN ENTIRE KINDERGARTEN CLASS
UNACCOUNTED FOR.
A MAN WEARING FULL CAMOUFLAGE.
BLACK COMBAT GEAR, AND A
MILITARY STYLE VEST WENT INTO A
KINDERGARTEN CLASSROOM AND
OPENED FIRE WITH A CLOCK AND
SEMI AUTOMATIC 9-MILLIMETER
HANDGUN.
THEY SAID THAT 100 SHOTS WERE
FIRED.
WE HAVE NOT YET CONFIRMED ANY OF
THIS DIRECTLY WITH THE POLICE.
AN ENTIRE KINDERGARTEN CLASS IS
UNACCOUNTED FOR.
WE HAVE BILL DLEY NOW, WHAT ARE
YOUR THOUGHTS AND WE HAVE HEARD
SO FAR?
>> IT IS SO MUCH TO ABSORB ON SO
MANY DIFFERENT LEVELS.
AMONG LAW ENFORCEMENT
STANDPOINT, WHAT THEY ARE DOING
RIGHT NOW AS THEY GO TO THROUGH
THIS, IT HAS TO BE TERRIFIC.
THESE PARENTS AND FAMILY ARE
RELATED AND TO GO TO ONE OF
THESE CRIME SCENES IS VERY
EMOTIONAL TO THEM AS THEY CARRY
OUT THEIR DUTIES.
ONE OF THE THINGS WE ARE HEARING
NOW IS THAT THERE IS POTENTIALLY
A SECOND PERSON.
WE DIDN'T KNOW THAT THERE WAS A
PERSON THAT WAS CARRYING OUT
THIS ACT.
PROVIDING SOME KIND OF AIDING
AND ABETTING TO THIS INDIVIDUAL
WHO ENTERED THE SCHOOL.
WE ALWAYS ASK WHY.
THE BIG WHY QUESTION.
I'M SURE THEY'LL COME OUT IN
TIME.
RIGHT NOW, IT IS A CRIME SCENE
THAT HAS NOW BEEN PUT UNDER
CONTROL WITH THE DEVASTATION
THAT THIS PERSON HAS LEFT
BEHIND.
IT IS UP TO THE POLICE WE PUT
TOGETHER WHAT HAPPENED.
MAYBE EVEN OUT THE PERPETRATORS
HOME, WHICH SOUNDS LIKE IT COULD
EVEN BE NEW JERSEY.
WHAT WOULD THIS PERSON TO COMMIT
THIS ACT.
IT SOUNDS VERY PERSONAL AND VERY
SPECIFIC.
WHAT IS THE CONNECTION?
THERE ARE EVEN SUGGESTIONS THAT
MAY HAVE BEEN A FATHER OR A
RELATIVE.
THESE ARE ALL UNCONFIRMED.
THERE IS A LOT OF INFORMATION
FLOATING AROUND AT THIS TIME.
I THINK THE KEY THING HERE IS
THAT AS THEY GO THROUGH IT, THEY
WANT TO MAKE SURE THEY HAVE
SECURED THE SITE.
THERE IS A SECOND PERSON, LIKE
WE SAW IN AURORA, COLORADO,
THEN THEY WILL DEAL WITH THAT
AND TAKE CARE OF.
MEGYN: ON THE PHONE WITH US NOW
WE HAVE A MOTHER OF A STUDENT AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR BEING WITH
US.
HOW OLD IS YOUR CHILD, AND IF HE
OR SHE WITH YOU.
>> MY DAUGHTER IS EIGHT YEARS
OLD.
SHE IS IN THE NEXT ROOM.
MEGYN: THANK GOD.
HOW DID YOU HEAR THE NEWS THIS
MORNING?
>> WE RECEIVED A TOWNWIDE CALL
FROM THE SCHOOL BOARD THAT THERE
HAD BEEN A SHOOTING IN THE
SCHOOLS WERE ON LOCKDOWN.
BUT THEY DID NOT SAY WHERE THE
SHOOTING WAS.
BECAUSE WE HAVE HAD AN EVENT
LIKE THIS HAPPEN BEFORE.
THERE WAS A SHOOTING NEAR A
SCHOOL.
IT HAD NOTHING TO DO WITH THE
SCHOOL, THEN I RECEIVED A TEXT
ALERT ON MY PHONE THAT THERE WAS
A SHOOTING AT A SCHOOL ON
DICKINSON.
THAT IS WHERE MY DAUGHTER GOES
TO SCHOOL.
SO I TALKED TO THE PARENTS OF A
NEW AND THEY SAID THAT THERE
WERE CHILDREN BEING CARRIED OUT
ALL BLOODIED.
THEY THOUGHT THEY WERE DEAD.
I WENT INTO TOTAL PANIC.
I WAS NUMB.
I GRABBED MY DAUGHTER AND IT WAS
THE HAPPIEST MOMENT OF MY ENTIRE
LIFE.
THE HAPPIEST MOMENT.
BUT NOW BEING AWARE OF THE
CHILDREN THAT WERE KILLED, I AM
DEVASTATED.
MEGYN: DID YOU HAVE THE
OPPORTUNITY TO SEE THE OTHER
PARENTS AT THE FIREHOUSE?
>> I SAW OTHER PARENTS AND
TEACHERS AND I TALK TO THEM.
I ASKED WHAT HAPPENED.
ANOTHER MOTHER THAT I KNEW SAID
SHE WAS IN THE SCHOOL, AND I
SAID ARE YOUR GIRLS ARE RIGHT.
SHE SAID THEY ARE FINE, BUT A
MASKED GUNMAN CAME IN AND
STARTED FIRING THAT THE
PRINCIPLE IS DEAD.
I SAID THE PRINCIPLE IS DEAD?
THIS IS A VIVACIOUS WOMAN WHO
LOVED CHILDREN.
SHE WAS THE BEST PRINCIPLE,
OKAY?
IT IS JUST HARD TO BELIEVE.
YOU DO NOT EXPECT IT ANYWHERE.
IT'S TERRIBLE WHEN IT HAPPENS
ANYWHERE.
BUT UCR QUAINT LITTLE DOWNTOWN
HERE IN SANDY HOOK, IT IS JUST
CRAZY.
MEGYN: YOUR DAUGHTER IS EIGHT
YEARS OLD, HOW DO YOU HELP HER
UNDERSTAND?
>> SHE'S RIGHT HERE, SHE'S OKAY.
THEY DIDN'T KNOW WHAT WAS
HAPPENING UNTIL THEY GOT INTO
THE FIREHOUSE.
THEY REALIZE THAT WHAT WAS GOING
ON.
BUT I STILL DON'T KNOW MY
FRIENDS CHILDREN, IF THEY ARE
OKAY.
I TRY TO CALL SOME PEOPLE, THEY
ARE NOT ANSWERING THEIR PHONE.
MEGYN: WHAT IS THE AVERAGE CLASS
SIZE IN THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL?
>> PROBABLY 16 OR 17 STUDENTS.
A LOT OF STUDENTS, BUT A SMALL
COMMUNITY SCHOOL.
MEGYN: WHEN YOU HEAR
CHILDREN HAVE DIED IN A
KINDERGARTEN CLASS UNACCOUNTED
FOR -- DOES THAT MAKE SENSE TO
YOU IN TERMS OF NUMBERS?
>> YES, ABSOLUTELY.
MEGYN: PC THE CHILDREN AND THE
COMMUNITY REVOLVES AROUND THE
SCHOOLS.
ESPECIALLY A COUNTRY SCHOOL TO A
LARGE EXTENT.
HOW DO YOU FUNCTION?
HOW DO YOU GO ON FROM HERE?
>> PERSONALLY I FEEL GUILTY EVEN
TALKING TO YOU AND THE OTHER
NEWS OUTLETS BECAUSE I FEEL I
SHOULD RESPECT THE FAMILIES AND
THOSE WHO WERE KILLED.
I DON'T KNOW IF THEY ARE FRIENDS
OF MINE WERE FRIENDS OF MY
DAUGHTERS.
-- I FEEL TERRIBLE.
ESPECIALLY AROUND CHRISTMAS
TIME.
MEGYN: THAT IS THE THING.
WE ARE IN THE MIDDLE OF, TO AN
11 DATE FOR CHRISTMAS.
>> EXACTLY.
MEGYN: IT APPEARS THAT WE ARE
WAITING FOR OFFICIAL NEWS
CONFERENCE ABOUT 26 THE 26
PEOPLE THAT ARE DEAD, INCLUDING
18 CHILDREN.
HAD THERE BEEN ANY REPORTS OF
TROUBLE?
ANY PARENT MAKING TROUBLE?
ANYONE -- YOU KNOW, SOMETIMES IN
A SMALL COMMUNITY PEOPLE ARE
CONCERNED ABOUT ONE PERSON.
>> NO, NOT AT ALL.
NOTHING.
IN THE SCHOOL YOU HAVE TO BUS
YOURSELF IN.
SECRETARIES CAN SEE YOU.
THEY BUZZ YOU IN.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT SOMEONE THEY
RECOGNIZE.
THEN PERHAPS -- I DON'T THINK
THEY WOULD LET SOMEONE IN WITH
MASS.
MEGYN: THAT IS A GOOD POINT.
BRENDA, I THINK YOU SO MUCH AND
I'M HAPPY FOR YOU THAT YOUR
LITTLE GIRL IS OKAY.
>>  THANK YOU AND GOODBYE THE
ONE BRINGING THE LATEST, WE ARE
GETTING REPORTS NOW.
DURING THE PRESS CONFERENCE MAY
BE DELAYED JUST A BIT.
OBVIOUSLY, THEY WERE SUPPOSED TO
START AT 1:00 O'CLOCK.
WE ARE TOLD WITHIN THE HOUR.
WE BELIEVE IT IS SOMETHING SOON.
NOW WE CHECK IN WITH TRACE
GALLAGHER.
REPORTER: NBC NEWS HAS JUST
REPORTED THAT THERE WAS A SECOND
SHOOTER.
WE MENTIONED EARLIER THAT THE
PURPLE VAN WAS SURROUNDED IN
DANBURY, JUST A FEW MILES AWAY
FROM SANDY HOOK.
NOW, WE ARE BEING TOLD THAT, IN
FACT, THERE IS A SECOND GUNMAN
IN CUSTODY.
KEEP IN MIND, THERE ARE ALSO
REPORTS OUT THERE THAT ONE OF
THE GUNMAN WALKED IN THERE THAT
HAVE MILITARY STYLE CAMOUFLAGE
AS WELL AS A FULL BODY ARMOR,
NOW THERE OUR REPORTS ABOUT FOR
WEAPONS BEING INVOLVED.
UNCLEAR IF THEY ARE TO WEAPONS
PER SHOOTER, EARLIER THERE WERE
REPORTS THAT SOMEONE HAD BEEN
PULLED OUT BY THE WOODS NEAR THE
SCHOOL.
THAT PERSON WAS WEARING
CAMOUFLAGE PANTS.
AS SOON AS THEY PULLED THE MAN
OUT OF THE WOODS, HE TURNED TO
THE POLICE, AND THE PARENTS THAT
WERE THERE SAID I DID NOT DO IT.
SO IT IS UNCLEAR IF THAT MAN MAY
BE CONNECTED.
WE ARE WORKING TO CONFIRM THIS.
NOW, THE REPORTS ARE FOR TWO
NETWORKS THAT THERE IS A SECOND
SHOOTER THAT HAS BEEN TAKEN INTO
CUSTODY.
MEGYN: GOING BACK TO BILL DALEY,
WHAT DOES THAT TELL YOU?
WE ARE USING THE TERM SECOND
SHOOTER, THAT IS WHAT OTHER NEWS
OUTLETS ARE DESCRIBING HIM AS.
>> YOU KNOW, AS MUCH AS THERE IS
A DISTINCTION THERE, WE ARE
TALKING ABOUT SOMEONE WHO
APPEARS TO BE COMPLICIT.
THEY ARE SUGGESTING THAT HE WAS
INVOLVED AND HE WAS SPORTING
SOME FASHION, WE DON'T KNOW
WHETHER HE WAS IN THE BUILDING
OR NOT, THERE ARE SINGLE
INDIVIDUALS HAVE A CERTAIN EVENT
AND FOCUS OF WHAT THEY WANT TO
DO.
SOME KIND OF PERSONAL CONNECTION
THAT DRIVES THEM TO COMMIT THESE
ACTS, WHATEVER THAT CONNECTION
IS.
IN THIS CASE, I THINK THAT
SOMEBODY WHO WILLINGLY WENT
ALONG AND PROVIDED SUPPORT,
AIDED AND ABETTED, IF NOT
COMMITTED THE ACTS, IS EVEN MORE
HORRENDOUS.
MEGYN: I WOULD LIKE TO BRING YOU
THE LATEST, THIS IS FROM THE
ASSOCIATED PRESS, WHICH IS NOW
REPORTING LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS CLAIM THAT THIS IS A
20-YEAR-OLD MAN, IT WAS A
20-YEAR-OLD MAN WHO WAS THE
SHOOTER.
AGAIN, FROM THE ASSOCIATED
PRESS.
WITH TIES TO CONNECTICUT SCHOOL.
OFFICIALS SAYING THAT THE GUN
USED IN THE ATTACKS IS A .223
CALIBER RIFLE.
AGAIN, NEW JERSEY STATE POLICE
ARE SEARCHING A PLACE THAT THEY
BELIEVE IS CONNECTED TO THE
SHOOTING.
IF IT IS THE HOME OF THE
SHOOTER, WE DO NOT KNOW.
BILL, DO YOU KNOW WHAT A .223
RIFLE IS?
>> IT JUST TELLS ME THAT THIS IS
SOMETHING THAT SOMEONE COULD
HAVE ACQUIRED AN IN NUMBER OF
DIFFERENT STORES.
MEGYN: IS THIS A SHOT ON?
>> IS USED FOR HUNTING AND OTHER
PURPOSES.
IT DOESN'T SUGGEST IT IS WHAT WE
HEARD.
MEGYN: A SEMI AUTOMATIC
9-MILLIMETER GLOCK --
>> YES, IT WOULD ALLOW HIM TO
SHOOT ROUNDS VERY QUICKLY AND BE
RELOADED VERY QUICKLY.
MEGYN: WE HAVE HAD WITH THE
LATEST FROM THE WHITE HOUSE.
REPORTER: AT KEARNEY, JAY CARNEY
JUST WRAPPED UP HIS SPEECH.
THE SHOOTING WAS TAKING PLACE
ABOUT 10:30 A.M. THIS MORNING.
THE BOTTOM LINE IS THAT JAY
CARNEY IS BEING CAREFUL.
HE IS NOT GETTING AHEAD OF THE
FACTS IN THIS CASE.
THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT WAS
WORKING WITH STATE AND LOCAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS TO DEAL
WITH THE EARLY STAGES OF THIS
INVESTIGATION.
HE DID NOT WANT TO CONFIRM
ANYTHING IN TERMS OF NUMBERS OR
HOW THIS SHOOTING PLAYED OUT.
HE ALSO DID NOT WANT TO GET INTO
HOW THE PRESIDENT PERSONALLY
REACTED TO THIS.
CLEARLY, YOU KNOW THAT THE
PRESIDENT IS A FATHER HIMSELF
AND REALIZES THE DEPTH OF THE
TRAGEDY.
THE PRESIDENT IS VERY LIKELY TO
COME OUT AT SOME POINT THIS
AFTERNOON AND ADDRESSES TRAGEDY.
MEGYN: IS IT POSSIBLE THAT WE
WILL HEAR FROM THE PRESIDENT
HIMSELF DRUCKER TODAY?
>> YES, IT IS VERY LIKELY.
I THINK HAVING BEEN TO THIS
BEFORE, WHERE THERE HAS BEEN
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS, PRESIDENT
BUSH, PRESIDENT OBAMA, WHERE
THEY WAIT A LITTLE BIT LONGER TO
FIGURE OUT THE FACTS AND FIGURE
OUT HOW DEEP THE TRAGEDY IS.
ONCE THEY HAVE A BETTER HANDLE
ON THAT, JAY CARNEY SAID IT WAS
LIKELY WE WOULD SEE THE
PRESIDENT COME OUT.
REPORTER: HERE IS JAY RNEY
MOMENTS AGO.
>> AT APPROXIMATELY 10:30 A.M.
THIS MORNING IN THE OVAL OFFICE,
THE PRESIDENT WAS NOTIFIED BY
HIS HOMELAND SECURITY ADVISER
JOHN BRENNAN OF THE SHOOTING IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE PRESIDENT HAS BEEN RECEIVING
MORE UPDATES ABOUT THIS
INCIDENT.
AS THE DAY PERCEIVES, AS WE GET
MORE INFORMATION, WE WILL
CERTAINLY PROVIDE IT TO YOU.
MEGYN: WE WILL GET BACK TO YOU
AS NEWS WARRANTS.
FOX NEWS HAS CONFIRMED THAT THE
SHOOTER IS A 20-YEAR-OLD MAN.
A 20-YEAR-OLD MAN WE DO NOT KNOW
WHETHER HE HAD A CHILD AND
THAT'S COOL.
WE WERE TOLD IT WAS CATERED FOR.
KINDERGARTEN USUALLY AROUND FIVE
YEARS OLD.
THAT DOESN'T MEAN THAT HE
COULDN'T BE THE FATHER OF A
STUDENT THERE.
IT DOES SEEM A LITTLE YOUNG, BUT
WE DON'T KNOW ENOUGH RIGHT NOW.
WE ARE BEING TOLD THE PRESS
CONFERENCE IS EXPECTED WITHIN
THE NEXT 40 MINUTES AND WE WILL
GET THE FIRST BRIEFING WE HAVE
HAD FROM THE PEOPLE WHO ACTUALLY
KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
THE LEAST BETTER THAN NOTHING.
NOW WE HAVE DR. KEITH ABLOW, HE
JOINS ME VIA SKYPE.
WE REALLY NEED TO HEAR FROM HIM
TODAY.
EVERYONE OUT THERE IS FEELING
DISCONCERTED AND SAT AND STARED.
WONDERING IF THIS IS THE SOCIETY
THAT WE LIVE IN, FEARING FOR THE
PARENTS OF LITTLE CHILDREN.
CAN YOU HELP PUT IT INTO ANY
SORT OF PERSPECTIVE FOR US?
>> AS TO THE FEAR AND THE SHOCK,
I UNDERSTAND.
THE RED LINE, BEYOND WHICH EVEN
THE BRAVEST WERE UNHINGED AMONG
US, THIS, KINDERGARTNERS, A
CLASSROOM PERHAPS OF THEM, THEY
ARE UNACCOUNTED FOR.
PERHAPS GONE.
THIS KIND OF SHOCK RESONATES
WITH PEOPLE BECAUSE IT SEEMS
LIKE THE UNTHINKABLE KEEPS ON
MOVING INTO THE SPHERE OF OUR
REALITY.
I THINK PEOPLE HAVE TO REACH OUT
TO THEIR KIDS.
THEY HAVE TO TELL THEM THAT IN
TERMS OF THE PROBABILITY OF IT
HAPPENING TO THEM, IT IS RARE.
ALSO, THEY SHOULD BE TOLD THAT
THESE THINGS DON'T COME OUT AS
BOGEYMAN.
THESE ARE SICK AND DEPRAVED
PEOPLE.
BUT THERE ARE WAYS THAT THEY CAN
BE IDENTIFIED SOONER AND WE WILL
WORK TO FIND THE WAYS AND WE
SHOULD WORK TO REBUILD OUR
MENTAL HEALTH CARE SYSTEM.
IN THE END, THERE WILL BE THINGS
THAT THIS PERSON SAID THAT FOLKS
AND THERE WILL BE THINGS THAT
PEOPLE SHAKE THEIR HEADS OUT AND
SAY, HOW DID THEY NOT ACT ON
THAT?
WE ARE REALLY NOT PREPARED TO
ACT ON THAT.
THE SYSTEM IN THE MENTAL HEALTH
CARE ARENA IS SO FULL OF HOLES.
SO FRAGMENTED AND FRAGILE.
SO UNDERFUNDED.
SO I THINK THERE SHOULD BE A
WAKE-UP CALL TO REBUILD THAT.
AND THEN WE SHOULD LET CHILDREN
HELP OTHER KIDS.
WE SHOULD GIVE THEM SOMETHING TO
DO WITH THEIR GRIEF AND FEAR TO
REACH OUT TO THESE OTHER
FAMILIES.
THESE OTHER FAMILIES AND KIDS,
AND DO SOMETHING TO TRY TO
REASSURE THEM AND SHOW THEM THAT
THEY CARE.
MEGYN: YES, TRYING TO EMPOWER
THEM IN SOME WAY AREA TO TALK
ABOUT THE RED LINES.
IT IS WELL PUT.
EVEN THOUGH YOU KNOW THERE IS
DEPRAVITY AND EVIL IN THE
SOCIETY, YOU'D LIKE TO BELIEVE
THAT THERE ARE LINES THAT JUST
DON'T GET CROSS.
IS THERE REASON TO BELIEVE THAT?
A SOCIOPATH HAS NO EMPATHY.
THERE IS NO FEELING AT ALL.
THE REAL QUESTION IS WHY HAVE
THERE NOT BEEN MORE THINGS LIKE
THIS IN THE PAST, AND WHAT IS
MAKING THEM SEEM TO COME OUT NOW
>> WELL, YOU AND I HAVE SPOKEN
ABOUT THIS BEFORE BOTH ON AND
OFF THE AIR.
JUST AS A CULTURE AND SOCIETY,
IS BEING DIMINISHED BY THINGS
LIKE REALITY TV AND FACEBOOK.
TAKING PEOPLE TO A FICTIONAL
ROME.
I GUESS YOU COULD ADD COMPUTER
GAMES TO THAT.
NOW PEOPLE FEEL LESS FOR ONE
ANOTHER.
THEY CAN THINK OF THEM ALMOST AS
THIRD PARTIES OR ENTERTAINMENT
FIGURES WERE ANIMATED CREATURES.
FOR THE PEOPLE AMONG US WHO ARE
VULNERABLE TO ACTS OF VIOLENCE,
THOSE WHO ARE VIOLENTLY ILL, IF
YOU WILL, THAT MEANS THAT THEY
CAN CONSIDER OTHERS EVEN LESS
THAN EVER BEFORE.
SO IN GENERAL, OUR CAPACITY TO
RESONATE WITH EACH OTHER
STEALING IS BEING REDUCED, AS I
BELIEVE IT IS.
THE OUTLIERS ARE THAT MUCH LESS
ABLE TO FEEL ANYTHING.
THAT RED LINE WILL KEEP
SHIFTING.
SADLY, PRESIDENTS IS A TERRIBLE
THING FOR PEOPLE WHO ARE
INCLINED TOWARDS VIOLENCE.
WHAT IT DOES IS MOVE THE BAR.
ONCE YOU HAVE HAD ONE SHOOTING
IN A KINDERGARTEN, AND I HATE TO
EVEN SAY IT, AND YET AS A
SCIENTIST I KNOW IT, THERE COULD
BE OTHERS.
MEGYN: PEOPLE HAVE TO REMEMBER
WHAT HE SAID AT THE TOP.
STATISTICALLY THE ODDS OF
SOMETHING LIKE THIS HAPPENING TO
A CHILD OR YOUR FAMILY ARE VERY
RARE.
YOU THINK OF THE NUMBER OF
STUDENTS TO GO TO SCHOOL
EVERYDAY AND HAVE FOR DECADES IN
THIS COUNTRY, AND THEN A TRAGEDY
LIKE THIS HAS UNFOLDED.
I DO WANT TO ASK YOU IF THERE IS
ANYWAY OF MOVING FORWARD FOR
THESE FAMILIES?
EVERYONE HERE IS FEELING FOR
THESE FAMILIES.
FAMILIES OF ALL 26 KIDS DEAD.
TWENTY-SEVEN TOTAL, IF YOU COUNT
THE GUNMAN.
EIGHTEEN OF WHOM ARE CHILDREN.
I KNOW YOU SAY GIVE CHILDREN
HELP, AND OF THE MOTHERS AND
FATHERS AND SISTERS AND BROTHERS
OF THOSE CHILDREN.
HOW WOULD YOU WAKE UP TOMORROW?
HOW WOULD YOU HAVE YOUR
BREAKFAST AND FUNCTION IN THIS
WORLD?
>> WELL, THAT'S THE BEST THING,
BY THE WAY, YOU CAN TELL THEM.
THAT IS WHAT I WOULD TELL THEM
IN THIS OFFICE.
I CANNOT FATHOM THE DEPTH OF
YOUR GRIEF.
I GIVE YOU CREDIT FOR YOUR
COURAGE.
I THINK THAT SOMEWHERE OUT OF
YOUR INCREDIBLE WOUND CAN COME
EXTRAORDINARY SENSITIVITY, SUCH
THAT YOU WOULD BE AN INCREDIBLE
GIFT TO OTHER PEOPLE MIGHT.
YET I HESITATE TO EVEN ASK THAT.
KNOWING NOW HOW MUCH THEY ARE
SUFFERING, AND I KNOW THAT IT'S
POSSIBLE.
BUT I DON'T PRETEND TO KNOW
EVERYTHING THAT YOU ARE FEELING,
AND I INVITE YOU TO TELL ME.
PLEASE TELL ME, BECAUSE SILENCE
IS THE ENEMY OF HEALING.
MEGYN: YOU KNOW, SADLY WE HAVE
17 OTHER FAMILIES OF CHILDREN
THAT NEED TO BE COMFORTED.
NOT TO DIMINISH THE REPORTS OF
THE DECEASED ADULTS.
WE HEARD ONE MOTHER'S TESTIMONY
ABOUT A YOUNG VIBRANT WOMAN.
SO OFTENTIMES THE ADULTS AND
VICTIMS GET OVERLOOKED.
EACH LOSS IS PROFOUND.
THE ODDS ARE THOSE DEAD ADULTS
HAVE FAMILIES AS WELL.
PLEASE DON'T GO AWAY, DOCTOR, WE
NEED YOU.
THERE IS A LOT OF INFORMATION
THAT WILL BE COMING OUT AS WELL.
WE STILL HAVE THE LEEWAY HERE
AND I WOULD LIKE TO GET LIVE TO
TRACE GALLAGHER AS WELL.
HE HAS A NEW NEWS DEVELOPMENT.
A HOME THAT IS BEING SEARCHED
NEAR THE SHOOTING SCENE.
REPORTER:
>> WE DO KNOW, IN FACT, THEY
HAVE CONFIRMED THAT A SECOND
PERSON IS BEING QUESTIONED.
WE DO NOT YET KNOW IF THAT
PERSON HAS BEEN TAKEN INTO
CUSTODY OR ARRESTED.
THAT CERTAINLY HAS BEEN
QUESTIONED.
THERE ARE REPORTS THAT IT WAS,
IN FACT, THE MAN, WHO WE SAID
EARLIER WAS BROUGHT OUT OF THE
WOODED AREA BY THE SCHOOL AND
THEN TURNED TO A PARENT AND, I
DID NOT DO IT.
THAT IS A PERSON WHO IS BEING
QUESTIONED.
NO WORD IF HE IS A SUSPECT OR A
PERSON OF INTEREST.
ON TOP OF THAT, AS HE SAID,
THERE IS NO HOME REPORTEDLY
BEING SEARCHED IN NEWTOWN.
THAT HOME BEING SEARCHED,
AUTHORITIES SAY IS CONNECTED TO
THIS SHOOTING.
AGAIN, WE TALKED ABOUT A PURPLE
VAN BEING SURROUNDED EARLIER BY
AUTHORITIES.
WE HAVE NOT HEARD ANYTHING ELSE
ABOUT THAT.
WE ARE GETTING MORE INFORMATION
ABOUT THE CHAIN OF EVENTS.
APPARENTLY WHAT HAPPENED IS THE
SHOOTER WENT INTO THE
PRINCIPAL'S OFFICE FIRST.
WHEN THE SHOOTING HAPPENED, THE
MORNING ANNOUNCEMENTS WERE
UNDERWAY, AND APPARENTLY THE
REST OF THE SCHOOL COULD HEAR
THE VIOLENCE IN THE SHOOTING
OVER THE SCHOOL INTERCOM.
AS YOU SAID AS FAR AS CLASS
SIZE, WE HAVE CONFIRMED THAT
THERE ARE TWO KINDERGARTEN
CLASSES AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
BOTH OF THOSE CLASSES HAVE 17
STUDENTS EACH IN THERE.
WE KNOW THAT CHILDREN HAVE BEEN
KILLED.
THE NUMBERS APPARENTLY ARE VERY
MUCH IN SYNC, AND AN ENTIRE
KINDERGARTEN CLASS REMAINS
UNACCOUNTED FOR.
MEGYN: TRACE GALLAGHER, THANK
YOU.
BRING YOU THIS INFORMATION FROM
WASHINGTON.
TWO SOURCES SAYING, WHICH IS NOT
UNEXPECTED, THIS IS NOT TO
BELIEVE IT THE TERRORISM IS
GOING ON IN THIS COUNTRY --
CLEARLY IT IS TERRORISM OF SOME
KIND.
IT WAS NOT TERRORISM BY SOME TO
HOTTEST GROUP.
WE WILL TRY TO GET MORE
INFORMATION ON THAT.
THAT IS WHAT WE ARE TALKING
ABOUT.
FOX NEWS HAS CONFIRMED THAT A
20-YEAR-OLD GUNMAN INITIAL
REPORTS SAID THAT HE WENT INTO
THE ADMINISTRATION OFFICE AND
THEN HE WENT DIRECTLY TO A
KINDERGARTEN.
AS WE AWAIT THE OFFICIAL WORD,
IS THAT HE WALKED INTO A
KINDERGARTEN CLASSROOM AND TOOK
OUT TWO OR FOUR OR WEAPONS.
YET A MILITARY STYLE VEST ON AND
STARTED SHOOTING.
REPORTER: LET'S GO TO THE PRESS
AND LISTEN.
MEGYN: THEY ARE JUST TESTING A
MICROPHONE.
WE ARE GOING TO GET THE
INFORMATION SHORTLY.
MEGYN: WE WILL PAUSE FOR ONE
MOMENT WHEN A FOX NEWS STATIONS
JOIN US NOW.
THIS IS COVERAGE OF THE DEADLY
SHOOTING COVERAGE IN
CONNECTICUT.
WE ARE NOW GETTING OUR FIRST
BRIEFING READING FROM THE
OFFICIALS ON SCENE.
LET'S LISTEN.
>> WE WOULD LIKE TO GET
INFORMATION AS QUICKLY AS
POSSIBLE.
THE GOVERNOR'S CHIEF CONCERN IS
MAKING SURE THAT THE FAMILIES
HAVE INFORMATION AS QUICKLY AS
POSSIBLE.
THAT IS WHERE HE IS NOW.
THIS IS LIEUTENANT PAUL DANS
FROM THE STATELY.
>>  THANK YOU.
WE WILL SET UP REGULAR PRESS
BRIEFINGS AS APPROPRIATE.
JUST AFTER 9:30 A.M. THIS
MORNING, NEWTOWN POLICE RECEIVED
A 911 CALL FOR AN EMERGENCY AT
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE NEWTOWN PD, WE CONTACTED THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE AND
SURROUNDING LOCAL POLICE
DEPARTMENTS.
ON AN OFF-DUTY TROOPERS
RESPONDED TO THE SCHOOL.
AND NEWTOWN POLICE, IMMEDIATELY
UPON ARRIVAL, ENTER THE SCHOOL
AND BEGAN A COMPLETE ACTIVE
SHOOTER SEARCH OF THE BUILDING.
THAT INCLUDED CHECKING EVERY
DOOR, EVERY CRACK AND CREVICE
AND PORTION OF THE SCHOOL.
THE MAIN OBJECTIVE WAS TO
EVACUATE AS QUICKLY AND
EFFICIENTLY AS POSSIBLE.
ANY AND ALL STUDENTS, AND
FACULTY IN THE SCHOOL.
THE ENTIRE SCHOOL WAS SEARCHED.
THE STAGING AREA WAS SET UP.
THE STUDENTS AND STAFF WERE PUT
INTO THAT STAGING AREA.
SOON THEREAFTER, THE CHILDREN
AND STAFF ARE WE UNITED WITH HER
PARENTS AND LOVED ONES.
THERE WERE SEVERAL FATALITIES AT
THE SCENE.
BOTH STUDENTS AND STAFF.
THERE IS NO INFORMATION RELATIVE
TO THAT.
THE SHOOTER IS DECEASED INSIDE
THE BUILDING.
THERE IS A GREAT DEAL OF WORK
THAT IS UNDERTAKEN IMMEDIATELY
UPON LOCATING THE SHOOTER, AND
THAT IS THERE IS A GREAT DEAL OF
SEARCH ONE ACTIVITY, A GREAT
DEAL OF LAW ENFORCEMENT
ACTIVITY, BOTH IN AND OUT OF
STATE TO MAKE SURE THAT WE COVER
ALL THE BASES RELATIVE TO THE
SPECIFIC INDIVIDUAL.
SUFFICE IT TO SAY, THE SCENE IS
SECURE.
STATE POLICE AND THE NEWTOWN
POLICE DEPARTMENT AND DANBURY
BEAUTY ARE WORKING TO ANSWER THE
QUESTIONS ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED.
AS WAS SAID, WE WILL KEEP YOU
BREATHED AND INFORMED ON A
REGULAR BASIS.
WE WILL PUT EVERYTHING OUT VIA
OUR WEBSITE WITH THESE PRESS
CONFERENCES.
I TURN IT BACK OVER NOW.
>> THE GOVERNOR TO CALL FROM
PRESIDENT OBAMA, A LITTLE WHILE
AGO, HE CALLED TO HIS EXPRESS
HIS CONDOLENCES ON BEHALF OF THE
NATION AND HIMSELF.
HE PLEDGED WHATEVER RESOURCES
THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT CAN BRING
TO BEAR TO ASSIST THE FAMILIES
AND THE INVESTIGATION.
WE WILL GET YOU INFORMATION AS
SOON AS WE CAN GET THE FAMILIES
THE INFORMATION.
THAT IS WHERE THE GOVERNOR IS.
AT SOME POINT LATER TODAY THE
GOVERNOR WILL BE HERE AND WE
WILL SET UP REGULAR BRIEFINGS.
THANK YOU.
[INAUDIBLE CONVERSATIONS]
>> AGAIN, NO QUESTIONS AT THIS
TIME.
I APOLOGIZE OR IT WE ARE NOT
ABLE TO ANSWER ANY QUESTIONS.
THE SCENE AND SECURE.
THE SITUATION IS SECURE.
WE WILL NOTIFY YOU SHORTLY WHEN
WE COME BACK FOR ANOTHER
BRIEFING.
AS QUICKLY AS WE CAN.
MEGYN: PRECIOUS LITTLE
INFORMATION COMING FROM THE
SCENE OF A DEVASTATING SCHOOL
SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WHERE AUTHORITIES
CONFIRM THERE HAVE BEEN SEVERAL
FATALITIES, INCLUDING STUDENTS
AND STAFF AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL THIS MORNING.
THE DISTRESS CALL CAME IN
SHORTLY AFTER 9:00 A.M. EASTERN
TIME.
THEY DID CONFIRM THAT THE
SHOOTER IS DECEASED AND THE
BUILDING.
WE ARE WORKING TO TRACK DOWN
RECORDS OF A SECOND SUSPECT
SOMEHOW INVOLVED IN THIS.
WE BELIEVE IS BEING QUESTIONED
BY LAW ENFORCEMENT ON A SECOND
LOCATION.
WE ARE TRYING TO TRACK THAT DOWN
TO CONFIRM EXACTLY WHAT, IF ANY
ROLE, THAT PERSON THE ECONOMIST.
YOU HEARD THE LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICER THERE, LIEUTENANT PAUL
DAVIS SAID THAT THEY DO NOT
BELIEVE THE PUBLIC IS IN DANGER.
BUT THAT THEY ARE PURSUING ARE
TORN ACTIVITY AND LAW
ENFORCEMENT ACTIVITY IN AND OUT
OF THE STATE.
AT THIS HOUR, WE HAVE CONFIRMED
INDEPENDENTLY THAT 27 PEOPLE ARE
DEAD, INCLUDING THE GUNMAN.
TWENTY-SIX VICTIMS, 18 PEOPLE OF
WHOM ARE CHILDREN.
WE BELIEVE THE VAST MAJORITY, IF
NOT ALL OF THEM WERE IN A
KINDERGARTEN CLASS INSIDE OF THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
A 20-YEAR-OLD MAN, FOX NEWS HAS
CONFIRMED, WENT INTO THE SCHOOL
AND STARTED SHOOTING AT LEAST
TWO WEAPONS, WHICH WE WERE TOLD
WERE SEMI- AUTOMATIC HANDGUNS,
INCLUDING A 9-MILLIMETER AND A
GLOCK.
WE WILL GIVE YOU MORE
INFORMATION FOR CONTINUING
COVERAGE.
I AM MEGYN KELLY IN NEW YORK.
MEGYN: GIVING LIFE TO BREAK
LEVENTHAL.
THE SHOOTER REMAINS INSIDE THE
SCHOOL THAT IS DECEASED?
REPORTER: THE OTHER KEY POINT,
THE PUBLIC NOT IN DANGER.
THEY WOULD NOT ADDRESS -- I
ASKED ABOUT A SECOND SUSPECT IN
CUSTODY, YOU HEARD THE STATE
POLICE WOULD NOT CONFIRM THAT.
WE ARE BEING TOLD BY OTHER
SOURCES THAT A PERSON IS BEING
QUESTIONED BY AUTHORITIES HERE
IN CONNECTICUT.
WE ARE TOLD THIS PERSON HAS NOT
BEEN ARRESTED OR TAKEN INTO
CUSTODY AT.
IT COULD BE SOMEONE THEY ARE
CONCERNED IS CONNECTED, BUT MAY
NOT BE.
THERE ARE A NUMBER OF LAW
ENFORCEMENT ACTIVITIES TAKING
PLACE RIGHT NOW, INCLUDING
SEARCH WARRANTS BEING SERVED ON
HOMES.
WE ARE TOLD THAT ONE OF THOSE
HOMES MAY BE IN CONNECTICUT.
ANOTHER MIGHT BE IN NEW JERSEY.
WE ARE ALSO TOLD THAT THE
SHOOTER HAS BEEN IDENTIFIED AS A
20-YEAR-OLD MALE.
THE POLICE WOULD NOT GET INTO
THE NUMBERS.
BUT WE HAVE TO REMEMBER THAT WE
ARE ROUGHLY FOUR HOURS SINCE
THIS MASS SHOOTING OCCURRED.
THERE'S A LOT THAT IS STILL NOT
PUT TOGETHER YET.
VERY EARLY IN THE INVESTIGATION.
AS WE SAID EARLIER, CRIME SCENE
IS VERY DIFFICULT AT THIS POINT
FOR THEM TO PROCESS.
THERE ARE SO MANY VICTIMS.
THE POLICE WOULD NOT CONFIRM THE
NUMBER, BUT WE HAVE BEEN TOLD BY
MULTIPLE SOURCES, INCLUDING
FEDERAL AGENTS, THAT THERE MAY
BE AS MANY AS 27 PEOPLE DEAD.
THAT INCLUDES POSSIBLY 18
CHILDREN.
EIGHT ADULTS AND THE SHOOTER, AS
WELL AS THE PRINCIPAL OF THE
SANDY HOOK OHMAN PRESCHOOL.
MEGYN: THANK YOU, RICK.
WE WILL GET BACK TO YOU
MOMENTARILY.
ONE OF THE WORST SHOOTINGS IN
U.S. HISTORY.
THIRTY-TWO PEOPLE DEAD AT
VIRGINIA TECH, NOW WE ARE BEING
TOLD THAT THE NUMBER IS 26
VICTIMS PLUS THE SHOOTER, AND
MAKES 27.
AT THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
IN CONNECTION WITH THIS CASE.
PRELIMINARY NUMBERS AS WE
CONTINUE TO AWAIT OFFICIAL
CONFIRMATION FROM THOSE WHO ARE
ON THE SCENE.
YOU CAN UNDERSTAND WHY THEY
DON'T WANT TO GIVE TOO MANY
DETAILS AT THIS TIME.
I'M SURE THERE ARE A LOT OF
FAMILIES GOING THROUGH A LOT
RIGHT NOW AND TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT WHETHER THEIR CHILD IS AMONG
THE DEAD.
BILL DALEY IS BACK WITH ME.
THE FBI IS NOW ASSISTING THE
LOCAL ON ENFORCEMENT WITH THIS
FOR THE WHITE HOUSE.
WHAT DID YOU PICK UP ON A?
>> AS MUCH AS WE'D ALL LIKE TO
GET MORE INFORMATION WITH
DETAILS, I THINK THE WAY THEY
APPROACH THIS IS NOT TO BE TOO
MUCH AHEAD OF THE CURVE.
TO NOTIFY THE NEXT OF KIN,
UNDERSTAND WHAT IS HAPPENING
BEFORE THEY SAY ANYTHING.
FROM OUR STANDPOINT, WE ARE
WONDERING WHAT ELSE IS GOING ON.
IT IS QUITE INSPIRING THAT
WITHIN A FEW HOURS, BUT THEY
MOVE VERY QUICKLY ON A NUMBER OF
DIFFERENT FRONTS.
THEY'RE PROBABLY GETTING
SUBPOENAS.
THE FBI IS INSISTING THAT LOCAL
LAW ENFORCEMENT GOES ACROSS
STATE LINES.
IN AN EFFORT TO GET MORE
INFORMATION ABOUT THIS
INDIVIDUAL, OR ANOTHER
INDIVIDUAL THAT THEY ARE
QUESTIONING.
THE LIEUTENANT WHO WAS SPEAKING,
IT MAY NOT MEAN THAT IT IS
CERTAINLY -- YOU KNOW, A FACT --
BUT HE DID NOT SAY THAT THEY
CONFRONTED THE GUNMAN WHEN GOING
INTO SCHOOL.
SO SUGGESTING THAT THE GUNMAN
WAS ALREADY DECEASED WHEN HE
WENT INTO THE SCHOOL.
AS HE WENT THROUGH HIS
WALK-THROUGH OF WHAT THEY DID
ROOM BY ROOM IN GATHERING THE
CHILDREN AND STAFF AND TAKING
THEM TO A SAFE AREA TO GET HIM
OUT OF SCHOOL.
I DON'T KNOW WHETHER THAT TELLS
US SOMETHING ABOUT YOUR GUNMAN
HAVING TAKEN HIS OWN LIFE, BUT
AS WE HEAR MORE ABOUT IT, THIS
GUNMAN WENT INTO THE SCHOOL AND
THERE WAS NO WAY TO STOP THEM.
THEY HAD SOME CLUES.
WE DON'T KNOW.
BUT THE SHOOTER WAS IN THERE FOR
A PERIOD OF TIME.
HE WAS WITH AUTOMATIC WEAPONS
AND HE FIRED ON CHILDREN AND
STAFF.
MEGYN: I KNOW YOU ARE NOT A
PSYCHIATRIST, BUT YOU HAVE BEEN
IN LAW ENFORCEMENT LONG TIME.
HAVE YOU START TO UNDERSTAND HOW
SOMEONE PUTS ON A MILITARY STYLE
DRESS AND TAKES AT LEAST TWO
SEMIAUTOMATIC HANDGUNS AND THOSE
IN THEIR AND STARTS EXECUTING
5-YEAR-OLD?
>> YOU KNOW, IN LAW-ENFORCEMENT,
YOU HAVE TO TAKE A STEP BACK.
MEGYN: HOW DO YOU UNDERSTAND IT
THOUGH?
HAVE YOU UNDERSTAND THAT?
HAVE YOU SEEN SOMETHING LIKE
THAT?
IS IT JUST A SOCIOPATH?
SOMEONE WHO CAN TAKE A LIFE --
THAT IS WHO THEY ARE?
IN YOUR HISTORY, HOW DO YOU
UNDERSTAND THAT KIND OF EVIL?
THE AMOUNT THE THING IS THAT YOU
CAN'T.
THERE ARE GOOD AND EVIL AND
PEOPLE HAVE CHOSEN EVIL.
THIS IS EVIL INCARNATE.
THAT IS WHY THE GOOD PEOPLE COME
TO PEOPLE WHO UP FOR WHAT IS
RIGHT AND GOOD, SUPPORTING EACH
OTHER, LOOKING AFTER EACH OTHER,
THEY ARE THE ONES THAT ARE GOOD.
EVIL IS ALWAYS THERE, AND THAT
IS WHY WE HAVE LAW ENFORCEMENT
AND TEACHERS AND OTHER PEOPLE
OUT THERE TRYING TO IDENTIFY
PEOPLE BEFORE IT HURTS OUR
CHILDREN.
SOMETIMES THAT PEOPLE DOESN'T
CATCH EVERYONE.
AND IT ISN'T AS SOLID AS WE
WOULD LIKE TO BE.
BUT WE KNOW THAT AS A RESULT OF
THIS, PEOPLE NEED TO GO OFF AND
DO GOOD THINGS.
CONTINUING TO DO GOOD THINGS TO
HELP EACH OTHER AND SOCIETY.
OTHERWISE PEOPLE WILL TAKE OVER.
MEGYN: STAND BY FOR JUST A
MOMENT.
JOINING US NOW IS A MOTHER WHO
LOST HER CHILD.
HER DAUGHTER, RACHEL, AND THE
COLUMBINE SHOOTING.
HER SON SURVIVE.
BETH, THANK YOU FOR BEING HERE.
WE NEED YOUR PERSPECTIVE AS WELL
TODAY.
WHAT ARE YOUR THOUGHTS AS WE
WONDER WHAT THE PARENTS ARE
GOING TO?
>> WELL, MY FIRST REACTION IS
I'M EXTREMELY ANGRY.
SO ANGRY.
ANGRY THAT A MAN WOULD KILL
BABIES.
AND THESE ARE JUST LITTLE
AS FAR AS THE PERISCOPE, THEY
ARE NOT GOING TO KNOW WHAT TO DO
FOR A LONG TIME.
WITH THE COLUMBINE SHOOTING, MY
SON CRAIG SURVIVED BUT RACHEL
DID NOT.
IT WAS LIKE THERE WERE TIMES
WHEN IT WAS REAL, AND OTHER
TIMES IT WASN'T AND YOU KIND OF
BLOCK OUT THE PAIN OF THAT.
THE ANGUISH OF THAT.
OR AT LEAST A YEAR OR POSSIBLY
MORE, THERE WERE TIMES WHEN I
WAS JUST GOING THROUGH THE
MOTIONS OF HAVING LOST RACHEL.
ALSO HAVING TO DEAL WITH A VERY
EMOTIONALLY CRIPPLED YOUNG MAN,
BECAUSE THIS GENTLEMAN WITNESS
ALL OF THE VIOLENCE.
AND THEN HIS SISTER WAS THE
FIRST ONE THAT WAS KILLED.
MY HEART RACES.
I JUST FEEL THAT THESE PARENTS
-- THEY ARE GOING TO HURT SO BAD
FOR SO LONG AND THERE'S THERE IS
NOT MUCH YOU CAN DO TO CONSOLE
THEM.
LOSING A LITTLE CHILD LIKE THIS,
IT MAKES ME VERY ANGRY.
IT MAKES ME EXTREMELY ANGRY
[CRYING]
MEGYN: IN THE SAME WAY THAT YOUR
DAUGHTER AND SON WERE TOTALLY
DEFENSELESS, THESE CHILDREN WERE
TOTALLY DEFENSELESS.
THE MOST DEFENSELESS YOU COULD
FIND ON THIS EARTH.
WE ARE TOLD THAT THERE ARE 26
INNOCENT VICTIMS IN ALL OF THIS.
INCLUDING THE 18 CHILDREN.
DID YOU FIND PEACE?
>> WE DID, BUT IT CAME MUCH
LATER.
BUT THERE DOES COME A DAY WHEN
YOU DON'T CRY ALL DAY LONG.
THERE DOES COME A DAY WHEN THE
SEVERE PAIN AND LOSS ISN'T
SELF-EVIDENT.
IT'S NOT SO PENETRATING.
BUT IT TAKES A LONG TIME TO GET
TO THAT POINT.
I WOULD LIKE TO OFFER HOPE THAT
RIGHT NOW THESE PARENTS CAN'T
IMAGINE HOPE.
ALL THEY UNDERSTAND IS THAT,
HAMAS.
EVEN THOUGH PEOPLE BELIEVE THAT
THINGS WILL GET BETTER.
THE TRUTH IS THAT IS NOT REALITY
TO THEM AT THIS POINT IN TIME.
IT WON'T BE A REALITY FOR A VERY
LONG TIME.
BECAUSE YOU CAN'T GET PAST THE
PAIN.
IT TOOK YEARS TO GET THERE,
THERE CAME A DAY WHEN I LAUGHED
AGAIN AND TALKING ABOUT RACHEL,
I COULD TALK ABOUT HER WITHOUT
BURSTING INTO TEARS OR HAD A
FLOOD OF EMOTIONS COME OUT.
AND WE FOUND SOME GOOD THINGS TO
DO.
WE HAVE CHANNELED OUR ENERGY AND
ANGER FOR WHAT HAS HAPPENED.
AND WE DID OUR BEST TO BE
POSITIVE AND WE WERE ABLE TO
TAKE RACIAL LEGACY AND USE IT
FOR SOMETHING VERY POSITIVE.
WHICH DID BRING FORTH HEALING.
THESE CHILDREN ARE TOO LITTLE.
TOO LITTLE TO HAVE ANYTHING LIKE
THAT.
THE BIRTHDAYS AND THEIR MOMENTS
-- THE LITTLE CHILDREN.
IT IS GOING TO BE EXTREMELY
DIFFICULT.
MY HEART IS BROKEN FOR THEM.
IT IS JUST BROKEN.
I WISH I COULD HELP THEM, BUT
THERE IS NO SHORTCUT.
NO SHORTCUT INTO SOMETHING OF
THIS NATURE'S.
MEGYN: IF THERE IS ANYONE WHO
CAN DO SOMETHING, MAYBE IT'S
SOMETHING LIKE YOU.
SOMEONE WHO HAS WALKED THROUGH
THE PAIN, AS THEY SAY.
COLUMBINE HAPPENED ALMOST 13
YEARS AGO, PEACE AND HAPPINESS
IS AT LEAST POSSIBLE.
FOR THE VICTIMS OF THESE
FAMILIES OF THIS TRAGEDY.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US.
THERE IS A LOT OF NEWS
UNFOLDING.
WE ARE GETTING DETAILS ABOUT THE
GUNMAN RIGHT NOW.
WE EXPECT TO LEARN SHORTLY WHO
IS WISE.
WE WILL BE BACK MOMENTARILY WITH
AN UPDATE AND MORE ON THAT.
THIS IS AMERICA.
WE DON'T LET FREQUENT HEARTBURN
COME BETWEEN US
AND WHAT WE LOVE.
SO IF YOU'RE ONE OF THEM PEOPLE
WHO GETS HEARTBURN
AND THEN TREATS DAY AFR DAY...
BLOCK THE ACID WITH PRILOSEC OTC
AND DON'T GET HEARTBURN
IN THE FIRST PLACE!
[ Male Announcer ]
E PILL EACHMORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBUR
TO TELL REAL PEOPLE ABOUT
OUR NEW 15 UNDER $15 MENU.
OH MY GOODNESS!
OH MY GOSH,
THIS LOOKS AMAZING!
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR NEW MAINE STAYS!
15ENTREES UNDER $15,
SEAFOOD, CHICKEN AND MORE!
OOTHE TILAPIAWITH ROASTEDEGETAB!
I'M ACTUALLY LOOKING AT
THE WO GRILLED CHICKEN
WITH PORTOBELLO WINE SAUCE.
AT PORK CHOP
WAS GREAT!
NO MORE
FAST FOOD FRIDAY'S!
WE'RE GOING TO GO
TO RED LOBSTER.
YEP.
[ Male Announcer ]
COME TRY OUR NEW MENU
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
SALAD, SANDWICHES, AND MORE.
MEGYN: FOX NEWS ALERT.
CHAOS AND FEAR AND HEARTBREAK AT
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
CONNECTICUT WHEN A GUNMAN WALKS
INTO THE BUILDING AND OPENS FIRE
WE BELIEVE ON A KINDERGARTEN
CLASS, LEAVING WE BELIEVE ,
LEAVING 26 PEOPLE DEAD INCLUDING
18 CHILDREN.
IT'S THE WORST SHOOTING TRAGEDY
EVER IN THE STATE OF CONNECTICUT
AND THE SECOND WORST IN U.S.
HISTORY.
IT ALL HAPPENED JUST AFTER
9:30 A.M. AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT JUST AFTER CLASSES
GOT UNDERWAY.
FOX NEWS CONFIRMING THE SHOOTER
WAS A 20-YEAR-OLD MAN WITH TIES
TO THE SCHOOL.
HE WAS REPORTEDLY DRESSED IN
BLACK COMBAT GEAR WITH A
MILITARY VEST AND HAT MULTIPLE
GUNS BETWEEN 2 AND 4.
A S.W.A.T. TEAM AMONG THE
THRONGS TO RESPOND TO THE
SCHOOL.
ALL OF THIS LESS THAN TWO WEEKS
BEFORE CHRISTMAS AND IN THE
MIDDLE OF HANUKKAH.
HERE IS LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE OF
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
DEPARTMENT MOMENT AGO.
>> I CAN GIVE YOU BASIC AND
GRIEF INFORMATION AS WE KNOW IT
NOW.
WE'LL SET UP REGULAR PRESS
BRIEFINGS AS APPROPRIATE.
JUST AFTER 9:30 THIS MORNING
NEWTOWN POLICE RECEIVED A 911
CALL FOR AN EMERGENCY AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AFTER OBTAINING INFORMATION WE
CONTACTED THE STATE POLICE AND
SURROUNDING POLICE DEPARTMENTS.
TROOPERS RESPONDED TO THE SCHOOL
AND NEWTOWN POLICE IMMEDIATELY
UPON ARRIVAL ENTERED THE SCHOOL
AND BEGAN A COMPLETE ACTIVE
SHOOTER SEARCH OF THE BUILDING.
THAT INCLUDED CHECKING EVERY
DOOR,ER CRACK, CREVICE AND
PORTION OFFED THE SCHOOL, OUR
OBJECTIVE WAS TO EVACUATE ANY
AND ALL STUDENTS AND FACULTY IN
THE SCHOOL.
ENTIRE SCHOOL WAS SEARCHED.
THAT WAS ACCOMPLISHED.
THE STAGING AREA WAS SET UP.
THE STUDENTS AND STAFF WERE PUT
INTO THAT STAGING AREA AND SOON
AFTER THE CHILDREN AND STAFF
WERE REUNITED WITH THEIR STAFF
AND LOVED ONES.
THERE WERE SEVERAL FATALITY AT
THE SCENE.
BOTH STUDENT AND STAFF.
THERE IS NO INFORMATION RELATIVE
TO THAT THAT BEING RELEASED AT
THIS TIME UNTIL WE MADE COMPLETE
PROPER NOTIFICATION.
THE SHORT IS DECEASED INSIDE THE
BUILDING.
THERE IS A GREAT DEAL OF WORK
UNDERTAKEN IMMEDIATELY UPON
LOCATE CAN THE SHOOTER.
THERE IS A GREAT DEAL OF SEARCH
WARRANT ACTIVITY TO INSURE WE
COVER ALL THE BASES RELATIVE TO
THAT SPECIFIC INDIVIDUAL.
SUFFICE IT TO SAY THE SCENE IS
SECURE.
STATE POLICE MAJOR CRIME SQUAD,
NEWTOWN POLICE DEPARTMENT, THE
STATE'S ATTORNEY AND MANY
AGENCIES ARE WORKING TOGETHER TO
ANSWER ALL THE QUESTIONS AROUND
WHAT HAPPENED.
WE'LL KEEP YOU BRIEFED AND KEEP
YOU INFORMED ON A REGULAR BASIS.
WE'LL PUT EVERYTHING OUT.
VIA OUR WEB SITE, AND WITH THESE
PRESS CONFERENCES.
MEGYN: THAT WAS THE LAST UPDATE
WE HAD.
RICK LEVENTHAL IS LIVE AT A PARK
NEAR THE SCHOOL.
>> Reporter: IMMEDIATELY AFTER
THAT I ASKED THE OFFICER WHETHER
HE HAD ANY INFORMATION ON A
SECOND SHOOTER, A POSSIBLE
ACCOMPLICE WHO MIGHT BE IN
CUSTODY AND HE WOULD NOT GO INTO
IT.
HE SAID SECOND ADDRESS THAT.
BUT HE DID SAY THE PUBLIC WAS
NOT IN DANGER.
THEY ARE QUESTIONING THAT PERSON
IS IN CUSTODY AND THAT PERSON
HAS NOT BEEN CONFIRMED AS BEING
RELATED TO THIS SHOOTING.
WE ARE HEARING OTHER SOURCES
WHICH ARE THE NUMBERS WHICH ARE
HORRIFIC.
27 DEAD, APPARENTLY 18 OF THEM
CHILDREN.
AN ENTIRE KINDERGARTEN CLASS
UNACCOUNTED FOR.
THE CLASSES RUN IN SIZE FROM
17-18 CHILDREN.
A GUNMAN WALKED INTO THIS
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND OPENED
FIRE ON A KINDERGARTEN CLASS AND
KILLED A NUMBER OF TEACHERS.
WE ARE TOLD THE PRINCIPAL AS
WELL BEFORE APPARENTLY KILLING
HIMSELF.
WE KNOW THE ENTIRE NEIGHBORHOOD
HAS BEEN SHUT DOWN AROUND SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
POLICE ARE BLOCKING THE ROADS.
THEY REUNITED PARENTS WITH THE
CHILDREN IN THE SCHOOL AND THERE
ARE 600 KIDS INSIDE THAT SCHOOL
WHO ATTEND THAT SCHOOL ON A
DAILY BASIS.
NEIGHBORHOOD SHUT DOWN.
THE SCHOOL ON LOCKDOWN.
THE ROOMS HAVE BEEN SEARCHED BUT
THERE IS A MAJOR CRIME SCENE
THAT MUST BE PROCESSED.
BODIES IN THE SCHOOL.
DIE GRAMS AND PHOTOGRAPHS THAT
MUST BE TAKEN BEFORE THAT SCENE
WILL BE CLEARED.
WE ARE LOOK AT A LENGTHY
PROCESS, PERHAPS DAYS.
WE ARE WAITING FOR FURTHER
UPDATES FROM THE POLICE HERE AT
THIS PARK CLOSE TO THE SCHOOL.
BUT WE CAN'T GET ANYWHERE NEAR
TO IT BRING YOU ANY MORE
INFORMATION ABOUT WHAT'S
HAPPENING INSIDE THOSE WALLS.
>> WE ARE GETTING MORE
INFORMATION ON THE WIRES HERE IN
STUDIO.
AND NONE OF IT IS GOOD.
JOINING ME NOW MARK FUHRMAN, A
FORMER L.A.P.D. POLICE DETECTIVE
AND FOX NEWS CONTRIBUTOR.
TALK TO ME ABOUT HOW THE POLICE
ARE SUPPOSED TO PROCESS THIS
CRIME SCENE.
>> AS DIFFICULT AS IT IS, THESE
MEN AND WOMEN HAVE TO PROCESS
THE MOST HORRENDOUS SCENE WHERE
CHILDREN ARE THE RECIPIENT OF
ADULT VIOLENCE.
IT'S TRAGIC BUT THEY HAVE TO GO
THROUGH IT.
SO WHEN YOU LOOK AT THIS SCENE,
CERTAINLY NOW YOU HAVE THE
HOMICIDE OF 26 PEOPLE AND THE
SUICIDE OF ONE, YOU HAVE TO
PROCESS THIS SCENE FOR THE
WEAPONS FOR THE SUSPECT.
YOU HAVE TO LOOK AT CERTAINLY WE
ARE TALKING ABOUT THE WEAPONS.
SO YOU HAVE TO KNOW WHAT CASINGS
FROM THESE SEMI-AUTOMATIC
WEAPONS ARE ON THE FLOOR, HOW
MANY CALIBERS WE ARE DEALING
WITH.
YOU HAVE TO ACCOUNT FOR THE
WEAPONS.
I HEARD YOU REPORT THERE WAS A
223 SUPPOSEDLY USED.
IF THAT IS THE CASE, THERE WOULD
BE RIFLE CASINGS ON THE FLOOR.
MEGYN: WHAT IS THAT?
>> IT'S AN AR PLATFORM.
IT'S A CALIBER OF A RIFLE ROUND
IT'S MOST PREDOMINANTLY IN A
TYPE OF MILITARY -- PARA
MILITARY PLATFORM.
MOST PEOPLE GENERICALLY CALL
THEM ASSAULT WEAPONS.
IT'S A SEMI-AUTOMATIC WEAPONS.
I'M NOT SURE THEY MAKE ANY
PLATFORM OTHER THAN PISTOLS.
I DON'T BELIEVE THEY DO.
IF THERE ARE THREE OR FOUR
WEAPONS ALL ACCOUNTED FOR, THEN
YOU COULD ASSUME OR AT LEAST
START TO SPECULATE THAT ONE
PERSON HAD ALL FOUR WEAPONS.
WERE THEY IN HIS POSSESSION.
WERE THEY IN CLOSE PROXIMITY TO
HIS BODY?
TWO SUSPECTS -- IF ONE SUSPECT
IS GONE AND THEY DIDN'T FLEE ON
FOOT, THERE WOULD BE A VEHICLE
MISSING.
THERE SHOULD BE A VEHICLE THAT
THE SUSPECT TRANSPORTED HIMSELF
TO THE LOCATION.
IT SHOULD STILL BE THERE.
THEY WILL ACCOUNT FOR THAT.
BUT THE PROCESS OF THE SCENE IS
A HOMICIDE AND WE DON'T KNOW AT
A LATER TIME -- IS THERE A
CONSPIRACY TO COMMIT THIS ACT?
WHAT IS THE MOTIVE OF THIS ACT?
DOES IT PERTAIN TO, INVOLVE
OTHER PEOPLE THAT ACTUALLY
SUPPLIED THIS MAN WITH ANYTHING
AND THEY KNEW THIS ACT WAS
ACTUALLY GOING TO TAKE PLACE?
IN OTHER WORDS, A CONSPIRACY.
SO THE INVESTIGATION AND THE
PROCESSING OF THE SCENE HAS TO
BE DONE CORRECTLY AND IT WILL
TAKE 2-3 DAYS AND THERE WILL
HAVE TO BE A TASK FORCE SET UP
BECAUSE YOU CAN'T EXPECT ONE
DETECTIVE OR ONE TEAM TO STAY UP
FOR 2 OR 3 DAYS.
THEY WILL GET RAGGED AND THEY
WILL MAKE MISTAKES.
SO THIS WILL TAKE SOME TIME.
IT WILL BE EMOTIONALLY TAXING ON
EVERYBODY THAT'S INSIDE THAT
SCHOOL.
MEGYN: I WANT YOU TO STAND BY
FOR JUST A MINUTE.
I'M TOLD TRACE GALLAGHER HAS
BREAKING NEWS AND IS FOLLOWING
INFORMATION REGARDING THE HOME
THAT WAS SEARCHED.
IS THAT THE CASE, TRACE?
>> Reporter: WE TALKED ABOUT
THIS HOME BEING SEARCHED.
WE HAD NO IDEA WHAT CONNECTION
IT WAS TO THE SCHOOL SHOOTER.
NOW ONE OF THE LOCALS IS
REPORTING THAT THERE WAS A BODY
THAT WAS FOUND INSIDE THAT HOME
IN NEWTOWN AND THEY ARE
INVESTIGATING WHETHER IT MIGHT
BE -- AND AGAIN WE SAY MIGHT
BE -- NONE OF THIS HAS BEEN
CONFIRMED -- THE BODY OF THE
MOTHER OF THE SHOOTER.
WE SAID THERE WAS A SECOND
PERSON OF INTEREST WHO WAS BEING
QUESTIONED BY POLICE.
WE HAVE NO WORD IF THAT PERSON
HAS BEEN ARRESTED OR TAKEN INTO
CUSTODY.
SIMPLY BEING QUESTIONED.
THAT WOULD IF YOU ARE CONNECTING
THE DOTS ELIMINATE THAT PERSON
AS BEING CONNECTED TO THIS NEW
TOWN, CONNECTICUT HOME.
REPORTS ARE THAT A BODY WAS
FOUND INSIDE THIS HOME AND IT
MAY HAVE BEEN THE MOTHER OF THE
SHOOTER.
AGAIN WE ARE GOING BY LOCAL
REPORTS.
SO WE WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT
VERY CLEAR.
TOP ADD ONE MORE EXCLAMATION
POINT.
A CAR BEING USED?
WE KNEW EARLIER A CAR WAS
CORDONED OFF AT THE ENTRANCE TO
THE SCHOOL.
IT HAD BEEN TAPED OFF.
UNCLEAR IF THAT WAS THE CAR OF
THE SHOOTER, ABOUT IT WAS PARK
THE RIGHT DIRECTLY IN FRONT OF
THE EXIT AND ENTRANCE TO THIS
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
MEGYN: KEEP WORK OUR SOURCES AND
BRING US THE INFORMATION AS YOU
GET IT.
WE NOW CONFIRMED THE IT WAS A
20-YEAR-OLD ARE GETTING INFORMA,
THERE ARE REPORTS ABOUT THIS
IDENTITY.
WE ARE NOT GOING TO GO WITH THAT
UNTIL WE KNOW FOR SURE THE
IDENTITY OF THE SHOOTER.
BUT I WANT TO ASK YOU, MARK.
WE CONFIRMED IT'S A 20-YEAR-OLD
MAN.
EARLIER THIS WEEK WE SAW A MASS
SHOOTING -- AN ATTEMPTED MASS
SHOOTING, TWO PEOPLE DEAD AT A
MALL OUT IN THE PORTLAND, OREGON
AREA.
THAT WAS A 22-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
>> I'M CERTAINLY NOT EQUIPPED TO
TELL YOU PSYCHOLOGICALLY WHAT'S
GOING ON.
I NEVER QUITE UNDERSTOOD MOST
CRIMES ON THE STREET.
BUT WHEN YOU LOOK AT THIS YOU
WILL BE ABLE TO GO BACKWARDS.
WHEN TRACE GALLAGHER WAS
REPORTING ABOUT FINDING A BODY
AT THAT HOME, POSSIBLY THE
MOTHER OF THE SHOOTER, THAT WAS
NOT A SURPRISE TO ME.
I SUSPECTED THEY WOULD FIND A
RELATIVE, A GIRLFRIEND OR WIFE
AT THAT LOCATION.
CERTAINLY THE FIRST THING THEY
DO IS TRY TO SECURE THE
SUSPECT'S LOCATIONS, DO SEARCH
WARRANT AND TRY TO CIRCLE THE
WAGONS AROUND ANY POSSIBILITY OF
SOMETHING THAT WOULD CONTINUE OR
TO COLLECT EVIDENCE.
BUT WHEN YOU LOOK AT THESE
SHOOTINGS, YOU KIND OF WONDER
WHAT IS THE CAUSE?
AND I KNOW PEOPLE ARE GOING TO
SAY GUNS.
BUT THAT'S NOT THE ISSUE.
IT'S THE PEOPLE -- WE WATCHED
THIS NATION BE BROUGHT TO IT'S S
ITS KNEES BY MEN WITH BOX
CUTTERS.
THAT NOT THE ISSUE.
IT'S THE PEOPLE.
TO BE CANDID.
I CAN COUPLE WITH NOTHING SHORT
OF MENTAL ILLNESS THAT WOULD
LEAD SOMEBODY TO THINK THEY WERE
GOING TO PROVE SOMETHING.
OR ACCOMPLISH SOMETHING EXCEPT
FOR IMMORTALITY IN THE MOST
BLACK AND BIZARRE AND MACABRE
WAY.
MEGYN: THE EXTREME COWARDICE OF
A MILITARY VEST AND COMBAT GEAR
TO GO IN AND EXECUTE A COUPLE OF
DOZEN 5-YEAR-OLDS.
THERE IS NO ONE WHO CAN HELP US
UNDERSTAND THAT.
BUT JUST THE SHEER ILLNESS AND
COWARDICE OF IT.
>> ONE MORE THING, MEGYN.
WHEN YOU HEAR THAT HE HAD
ALREADY KILLED OR MOST PROBABLY
KILLED HIS MOTHER AT A LOCATION
THAT HE PROBABLY LEFT FROM THIS
MORNING, HE KNEW THAT HE WAS
NEVER COMING BACK.
AN WHAT ELSE JUST --
MEGYN: BEFORE YOU FINISH THAT
THOUGHT WE ARE TOLD WE BELIEVE
THIS VIDEO IS THE POLICE OUTSIDE
OF THE HOME WHERE WE BELIEVE
THIS WOMAN'S BODY WAS FOUND.
INITIAL REPORTS ARE THAT IT MAY
BE A WOMAN LINKED TO THE GUNMAN,
POSSIBLY THE MOTHER.
ALL UNCONFIRMED.
GO AHEAD, MARK.
>> YOU JUST LOOK AT THIS.
HE WAS -- HE WAS TIDYING UP HIS
MENTALLY DISTURBED LIFE.
HE KILLED A PERSON AT THE
RESIDENCE THAT HE WAS EITHER
RELATED TO OR STAYED AT.
HE WAS NEVER COMING BACK THERE.
HE WAS NEVER LEAVING THIS CRIME
SCENE.
WHETHER HE WAS SHOT BY THE
POLICE OR HE TOTALLY AND
ABSOLUTELY ALWAYS INTEBLEDDED TO
TAKE HIS OWN LIFE.
YOU ASK ABOUT WHAT IS GOING ON.
I SEE ONE THING WE HAVE PEOPLE
THAT ARE GOING TO COMMIT SUICIDE
THAT SOMEHOW WANT TO BE LESS
ANONYMOUS IN THE REALM OF
SUICIDE AND MORE FAMOUS IN THE
AREA OF HOMICIDE.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND IT.
I NEVER UNDERSTOOD IT.
BUT IT IS THE FACT THAT THIS IS
THE SOCIETY WE LIVE IN NOW.
MEGYN: MARK, THANK YOU.
DR. ABLOW WILL BE BACK WITH US
IN JUST A BIT.
WE ARE GOING TO CHECK BACK IN
WITH HIM.
BUT I WANT TO GET TO AN EXPERT
ON SCHOOL SECURITY.
BOB, THANK YOU FOR BEING HERE.
YOUR THOUGHTS ON WHAT WE HAVE
SEEN.
>> HOW DO YOU PREPARE FOR
SOMETHING LIKE THIS?
AAS MUCH AS WE ARE IN SCHOOLS
AROUND THE WORLD, WE SET UP
PROTOCOL.
YOU LOOK AT THE RELATIONSHIP
BETWEEN THE POLICE DEPARTMENT
AND THE SCHOOL.
YOU LOOK AT THE CRIME STATISTICS
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
YOU LOOK AT YOUR PARENTS WHO
HAVE DOMESTIC VIOLENCE ISSUES.
THESE ARE PART OF A GOOD
SCENARIO TO BUILD A PREVENTATIVE
PROGRAM.
BUT WHEN YOU SEE SOMETHING LIKE
THIS, THIS IS ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE
TO PREVENT.
MEGYN: THEY HAD SECURITY IN
PLACE.
I KNOW YOU HAVE DONE SECURITY
FOR CONNECTICUT SCHOOLS.
THEY HAD A SECURITY SYSTEM WHERE
YOU HAD TO BE BUZZED IN.
THEY HAD TO SEE YOU ON THE
CAMERA BEFORE YOU GET INTO THE
SCHOOL.
WE ARE TOLD THE SHOOTER HAD
QUOTE TIES TO THE SCHOOL.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THAT MEANS BUT
SOMETHING FAILED.
>> THAT'S WHY YOU HAVE A CLOSE
RELATIONSHIP WITH YOUR
PSYCHIATRIST AND LOCAL POLICE
DEPARTMENT.
BECAUSE YOU WANT TO KNOW IF
THERE IS A DOMESTIC VIOLENCE
SITUATION IN TOWN.
THE SCHOOL AND THE POLICE HAVE
TO WORK WITH EACH OTHER IN ORDER
TO RESPOND.
IT IS SOMETHING THE POLICE ARE
AWARE OF.
WE DON'T KNOW HERE YET WHAT THE
CASE IS.
MEGYN: BUT THE ODDS OF THIS GUY
HAVING BEHAVED COMPLETELY
NORMALLY AND NOT HAVING HAD ANY
RED FLAGS PRIOR TO THIS DAY --
>> THEY ARE SLIM.
THERE HAS GOT TO BE SOME ISSUES
HERE.
THE POLICE ARE LOOKING THROUGH
HIS FACEBOOK AND TELEPHONE
CALLS.
THEY ARE LOOK AT THE HARD DRIVE
ON THE COMPUTER.
THEY ARE CHECKING EVERYTHING OUT
IN HIS PAST AND CURRENT PAST.
ONE TO MAKE SURE NO ONE ELSE IS
INVOLVED, THAT THERE IS NO OTHER
COCONSPIRATORS.
HOW DID HE GET TO THIS POINT,
HOW DID THIS HAPPEN?
MEGYN: WHAT CAN YOU SAY TO THE
PARENTS WHO HAVE KIDS IN SCHOOL.
YOU DON'T THINK ABOUT -- THERE
ARE AREAS IN THIS COUNTRY WHERE
SCHOOLS ARE NEAR WAR ZONES AND
IT'S A TRAGEDY AND A STORY IN
ITSELF.
BUT MOST PARENT SEND THEIR
CHILDREN TO SCHOOL AND THEY
DON'T WORRY ABOUT THEIR SAFETY.
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THEM NOW?
>> I CAN TELL YOU AS A CO-CHAIR
WITH THE TERRORISM TASK FORCE IN
NEW YORK, BEING INVOLVED WITH
DARE AMERICA WITH POLICE
OFFICERS GOING INTO THE SCHOOLS
ON A REGULAR BASIS IT'S A MATTER
OF HAVING THAT RELATIONSHIP AS
STRONG AS IT CAN BE IT'S MAKING
SURE THE PARENTS, THE TEACHERS,
THE SCHOOL BOARD, THE POLICE ARE
ALL WORKING IN CONCERT WITH ONE
ANOTHER.
YOU DO THE BEST NUK TERMS OF
PREVENTING A SITUATION LIKE THIS
FROM OCCURRING.
MEGYN: MOST SCHOOLS ARE SAFE.
>> SOME SCHOOLS HAVE METAL
DETECTORS.
THIS WAS A NICE LOVELY BEAUTIFUL
TOWN WHERE PARENTS LET THEIR
LITTLE CHILDREN GO TO SCHOOL IN
KINDERGARTEN AND FIRST GRADE TO
FEEL PERFECTLY SAFE.
MEGYN: LIKE MOST TOWNS AND
SCHOOLS IN AMERICA.
MOST TOWNS AND SCHOOLS IN
AMERICA CHOOSE TO LIVE AS A FREE
SOCIETY AND WE WON'T HAVE METAL
DETECTORS WHERE OUR 5-YEAR-OLDS
GO IN TO LEARN THE MOST BASIC
LESSONS.
SO THAT'S A DECISION WE MAKE.
BUT YOU HAVE TO HAVE SOME LINE
OF SECURITY.
HERE THE DAYS AND WEAKS AHEAD
WILL TELL US WHAT THE FAILING
WAS.
THAT'S NOT A JUDGMENTAL THING.
IT'S A LET'S LEARN FROM IT.
BUT IT APPEARS HE WAS BUDS IN
WHEN HE SHOULDN'T HAVE BEEN OR
PIGGY BACKED ON SOMEBODY.
SOMEHOW FOUND A WAY IN.
DO SCHOOLS NEED TO TAKE THIS AS
AN OPPORTUNITY TO REVISIT EVEN
THE MOST BASIC SECURITY
PROCEDURES THEY HAVE IN PLACE?
>> YES.
ONE OF THE FAILURES WE HAVE IS
WE TEND TO THINK BECAUSE WE ARE
IN A SAFE NEIGHBORHOOD AND WE
CAN GET OUT OF THE CITY AND GO
TO NEW JERSEY OR LONG ISLAND OR
CONNECTICUT OR ANYWHERE ACROSS
OUR COUNTRY WHERE WE ARE AWAY
FROM THE BIG CITIES AND AWAY
FROM THE CRIME POPULATION THAT
WE HAVE A SENSE OF SECURITY.
VERY OFTEN THOSE ARE THE AREAS
WHERE YOU NEED MORE SECURITY
BECAUSE YOU DON'T HAVE THE
POLICE OFFICER ON THE CORNER
WITH A WEAPON TO BE ABLE TO
SHOOT THIS GUY.
NO ONE WAS AROUND WITH A WEAPON
FAST ENOUGH TO KILL HIM.
MEGYN: DO MOST SCHOOLS HAVE A
SECURITY OFFICER.
>> MOST SCHOOLS HAVE A SECURITY
OFFICER FROM THE LOCAL DHOAPT IS
ASSIGNED TO THE SCHOOL.
BUT HE'S NOT IN THE SCHOOL ALL
DAY.
MOST OF THESE SMALL TOWNS MAYBE
HAVE 8, 10, 15 POLICE OFFICERS.
THEY HARDLY HAVE ENOUGH PART
TIME POLICE OFFICERS TO EVEN DO
THE DARE PROGRAM TO TEACH KIDS
ABOUT DRUGS AND VIOLENCE.
IT'S NOT LIKE YOU HAVE A
FULL-TIME POLICE OFFICER.
THE KIDS SOMETIMES IN THE DARE
PROGRAM WILL TELL THE DARE
OFFICER THEIR FAR IT IS VIOLENT,
THEIR MOTHER IS VIOLENT.
THEY HAVE A BROTHER OR UNCLE WHO
IS VIOLENT.
YOU GET INFORMATION BY
COMMUNICATING WITH THE KIDS.
MEGYN: THIS IS LOOKING LIKE IT
WASN'T THE FATHER OF A STUDENT.
HE'S ONLY 20.
WE DON'T KNOW.
IF THIS IS SOME RANDOM SHOOTING.
HE HAS SOME TIES TO THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
IF IT'S A RANDOM SHOOTING HOW DO
YOU FORESEE THAT AND PLAN
AGAINST IT?
>> IT'S HARD.
THAT'S WHY YOU DO THE BEST IN
TERMS OF THE CCTV AND A SYSTEM
TO LET PEOPLE INTO THE SCHOOL.
YOU BUILD PERIMETERS OUTSIDE THE
SCHOOL.
MEGYN: IT'S WHEN YOUR GUARD IS
DOWN AT SOMETHING HAPPENS.
>> IT MAY CHANGE THE WAY THAT WE
GO FLY ON AN AIRPLANE.
THIS MAY BE WHAT IT TOOK FOR
SCHOOLS TO WAKE UP AND CHANGE
THE WAY THEY CONDUCT SECURITY.
YOU DON'T GET NEAR THAT SCHOOL
WITHOUT GOING THROUGH PERIMETER
SECURITY.
WITH A GAIT GOING UP -- IF HE'S
DRESSED IN COMBAT GEAR AND
WEARING A MILITARY-STYLE VEST
AND HE HAS BETWEEN 2-4 WEAPONS.
A .223 CALIBER RIFLE.
NO ONE IS GOING TO BUZZ HIM IN
IF THAT'S VISIBLE.
THE POINT YOU MAKE ABOUT THE
POLICE IS AN INTERESTING ONE.
I HAVE TWO KIDS.
NOW I WANT TO SEE AN ARMED
POLICE OFFICER IN THE SCHOOLS.
I NEVER EVEN THOUGHT ABOUT THAT
TRIER TO NOW.
WHAT WOULD THAT TAKE TO HAVE AN
ARMED POLICE OFFICER IN EVERY
SCHOOL?
>> I THINK WE JUST SAW IT.
EVERY TOWN WE DEAL WITH WITH THE
DARE PROGRAM, IT HAS LOST ABOUT
A THIRD OF ITS TEACHING
CAPABILITY ACROSS THE COUNTRY
BECAUSE OF BUDGET CUTS IN LOCAL
MUNICIPALITIES.
IT'S A REALITY WE LIVE WITH.
BUDGETS ARE DOWN IN CITIES AND
TOWNS ACROSS OUR COUNTRY AND
THEY CAN'T AFFORD TO HAVE THE
PROGRAMS.
HOW ARE THEY GOING TO AFFORD TO
PUT A FULL-TIME POLICE OFFICER
INTO THE SCHOOL?
THEY WILL HAVE TO DO THE
PREVENTATIVE PROGRAMS WE
RECOMMEND FOR SCHOOLS IN TERMS
OF PERIMETER SECURITY.
CCTV.
ALL THAT WILL HAVE TO BE PUT
INTO PLACE.
IN ADDITION YOU MIGHT HAVE TO
HAVE A SECURITY OFFICER THAT
DOESN'T HAVE NECESSARILY NOT A
POLICE OFFICER BUT AN ARMED
SECURITY OFFICER.
MEGYN: IT COULD BE SOMETHING
PARENT PAY FOR.
>> I THINK LIT CHANGE THE WAY WE
LOOK AT THINGS.
FOR SCHOOLS THIS WILL BE WHAT
9/11 WAS FOR AIRPORTS.
MEGYN: I WANT TO GET TO TRACE
GALLAGHER WITH BREAKING NEWS.
>> Reporter: WE JUST CONFIRMED
THE SHOOTER IS IDENTIFIED.
HE IS 20-YEAR-OLD RYAN LANZA.
WE ARE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT.
WE HAVE SOME PICTURES AND
IDENTIFICATIONS.
WE WANT TO MAKE SURE WE HAVE THE
RIGHT GUY BEFORE WE PUT HIS
PICTURE UP ON THE AIR.
HE'S NOW THE SHORT AND
APPARENTLY ACCORDING TO OTHER
REPORTS HE LIVED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT IN FAIRFIELD COUNTY.
BECAUSE THE OTHER REPORTS WERE
POLICE WENT TO HIS HOME AND
REPORTEDLY FOUND A BODYNSIDE
THAT HOME THAT THEY ARE
INVESTIGATING THE POSSIBILITY
THE BODY MAY HAVE BEEN THE
MOTHER OF 20-YEAR-OLD RYAN
LANZA.
WE DO KNOW THAT IN FACT YOU CAN
SEE DIRECTLY BELOW ME, THIS IS A
PICTURE OF 20-YEAR-OLD RYAN
LANZA.
YOU SAID EARLIER HE HAD A
CONNECTION TO THE SCHOOL.
THE SCHOOL AT 9:30 GOES INTO
LOCKDOWN.
BEFORE YOU CAN GET IN THE FRONT
DOOR YOU HAVE TO BE BUDS IN.
THEY CAN SEE WHAT YOU LOOK LIKE
THEN YOU GIVE THEM A REASON WHY
YOU WANT TO COME IN.
IF THIS GUY WAS BUDS IN, IT'S
UNCLEAR.
WE ARE BEING TOLD RYAN LANZA IS
24 YEARS OLD.
THIS WOULD CHANGE THINGS.
WE WERE FIGURING OUT HOW WOULD A
20-YEAR-OLD HAVE A CONNECTION TO
THE SCHOOL IF HE DIDN'T WORK AT
THE SCHOOL.
IF YOU ARE 20 YEARS OLD IT'S
HIGHLY UNLIKELY YOU WOULD HAVE A
STUDENT WHO GOES TO THE SCHOOL.
IF HE IS 24 YEARS OLD, MAYBE
THIS IS NOT SOMEONE WHO WORKED
FOR OR WITH THE SCHOOL.
MAYBE THIS WAS A PARENT OF A
STUDENT AT THE SCHOOL.
WE ARE TRYING TO WORK ALL THAT
OUT.
HE WAS BUZZED IN THROUGH A NEW
SECURITY SYSTEM WHICH APPARENTLY
WAS JUST PUT IN PLACE A COUPLE
WEEKS AGO BUT HAS BEEN IN PLACE
IN MUCH OF FAIRFIELD COUNTY
WHERE YOU CANNOT GET IN THE
FRONT DOOR UNLESS YOU ARE GIVEN
CLEARANCE TO GET IN THE FRONT
DOOR.
MEGYN: STAND BY WITH ME.
I WANT TO UPDATE OUR VIEWERS.
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT JUST
AFTER 9:30 A.M. WE BELIEVE THIS
MAN, 24-YEAR-OLD RYAN LANZA WENT
INTO THE SCHOOL WEARING COMBAT
GEAR, A FULL MILITARY-STYLE VEST
AND HAD BETWEEN 2-4 WEAPONS
INCLUDING A GLOCK AND A
SEMI-AUTOMATIC.
WE BELIEVE HE FOUND HIS WAY INTO
ONE OF THE KINDERGARTEN
CLASSROOMS.
WE ARE TOLD AN ENTIRE
KINDERGARTEN CLASS REMAINS
UNACCOUNTED FOR.
WE ARE TOLD 27 PEOPLE ARE DEAD
IF YOU INCLUDE THE GUNMAN.
RYAN LANZA.
OF THE 26 INNOCENT VICTIMS.
18 ARE CHILDREN.
THAT IS OUR INFORMATION AT THIS
HOUR.
THERE HAD BEEN REPORTS THAT OVER
100 SHOTS WERE FIRED.
WE HAVE NOT BEEN ABLE TO CONFIRM
THAT.
WE DON'T KNOW HOW MANY SHOTS
WERE FIRED.
AND THE POLICE SAY THAT THE
SHOOTER IS DEAD INSIDE THE
CLASSROOM.
WE BELIEVE THAT THE BODIES OF
THE VICTIMS REMAIN INSIDE THE
SCHOOL AS WELL AS THE POLICE
CONTINUE TO PROCESS THE CRIME
SCENE AND WE ARE TRYING TO GET
MORE INFORMATION NOW ON REPORTS
OF A POSSIBLE SECOND SUSPECT.
KEEP IN MIND SOMETIMES THESE
THINGS COME DOWN AND THEY DON'T
TURN OUT TO BE ANYTHING.
BUT WE DID LEARN EARLIER THERE
IS A HOUSE NEAR THE SCHOOL IN
WHICH A BODY HAD BEEN FOUND AND
THERE WERE EARLY REPORTS THIS
PERSON MAY HAVE BEEN RELATED TO
RYAN LAND TODAY, PERHAPS HIS
MOTHER.
BACK TO TRACE NOW WITH MORE.
>> Reporter: YOU ARE TALKING
ABOUT MORE INFORMATION ABOUT
THIS SHORT.
WE JUST READ HIS FACEBOOK PAGE
AND MATCHED THE PICTURE.
HE IS 24 YEARS OLD.
HE LIVES IN HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY.
YOU HEARD RICK LEVENTHAL TALK
ABOUT HOW POLICE WERE SEARCHING
A HOME IN NEW JERSEY.
HE'S FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
HIS MOM LIVED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
HE LIVES IN WHO BROKEN, NEW
JERSEY.
WAS HE A FORMER STUDENT?
WHAT CAPACITY DOES HE HAVE A
CONNECTION TO THIS ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AND WHY WAS HE BUZZED IN.
THAT'S THE INFORMATION WE ARE
GETTING.
HE'S FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
BUT HE LIVES CURRENTLY OR
CURRENTLY LIVED IN WHO BROKEN,
NEW JERSEY.
AND THAT'S WHY AUTHORITIES ARE
ALSO IN NEW JERSEY SEARCHING THE
HOME THERE.
SO THE PUZZLE IS GETTING A
LITTLE BIT MORE PIECED TOGETHER.
BUT AS YOU MENTION, OTHER
POTENTIAL SUSPECT OR PERSON OF
INTEREST POLICE ARE TALKING TO.
WE HAVE GOTTEN VERY LITTLE MORE
INFORMATION ABOUT WHAT ROLE HE
MAY OR MAY NOT HAVE PLAYED IN
ANY OF THIS.
MEGYN: I WANT TO GO TO TONY
PERKINS WHO WE HAPPEN TO BE
FORTUNATE ENOUGH TO HAVE WITH US
TODAY.
HE'S THE PRESIDENT OF THE FAMILY
RESEARCH COUNCIL.
WHAT AN IMPORTANT DAY FOR FAITH
AND WHAT A CHALLENGE TO IT FOR
THOSE FAMILIES.
>> AS A FATHER OF FIVE KIDS MY
HEART IS BROKEN FOR THOSE
FAMILIES.
AS A FORMER POLICE OFFICER THAT
HAS BEEN AT CRIME SCENES BEFORE
I CAN ONLY IMAGINE THE STRESS
THESE OFFICERS WILL HAVE IN
PROCESSING THIS CRIME SCENE.
YOU ARE RIGHT, IN TIMES LIKE
THESE WE SEE COMMUNITIES ACROSS
THE COUNTRY TURN TO FAITH.
CHURCHES OPEN THEIR DOORS, THEY
REACH SOUTH.
IT'S PART OF THE GRIEVING
PROCESS AS THIS CONTINUES TO
UNFOLD.
MANY PEOPLE WILL BE TRYING TO
MAKE SENSE OF THIS AND YOU
CAN'T.
THERE ARE SOME THINGS IN LIFE
YOU SIMPLY CANNOT MAKE SENSE OUT
OF.
THIS ONE OF THOSE SENSELESS ACTS
OF VIOLENCE.
OUR STAFF IN WASHINGTON TODAY --
WE ARE GATHERING EVEN IN THIS
HOUR PRAYING FOR THESE FAMILIES.
MOST OF US HAVE KIDS.
AND EVERY AMERICAN IS TOUCHED BY
A TRAGEDY LIKE THIS.
MEGYN: THE FAMILY RESEARCH
COUNCIL WAS TARGETED NOT TOO
LONG AGO BY A MADMAN WHO SHOT
THE GUARD.
HE'S OKAY NOW.
>> HE'S BACK TO WORK.
MEGYN: YOU HAVE BENT VICTIM OF
VIOLENCE.
DR. ABLOW WAS ON EARLIER TALKING
ABOUT THE DEPRAVITY AND
DISCONNECTION PEOPLE FEEL FROM
SOCIETY.
BECAUSE WE HAVE BECOME SO
OBSESSED WITH ONLINE AND GAME OR
WASTE IS.
AMERICA LOOKS VERY DIFFERENT
THANKED 30 YEARS AGO.
WE DON'T INTERACT WITH EACH
OTHER THE WAY WE DID 30 YEARS
AGO.
FAITH HAS BEEN DIMINISHED AS
WELL.
FAITH HAS BEEN SOMETHING THAT'S
BEEN A COMMON THREAD IN AMERICA
THAT BOUND US TO ONE ANOTHER FOR
SO LONG.
>> IT HAS BEEN A COMMON THREAD
AND WE FIND TONIGHT TIMES LIKE
THESE.
IN TRAGEDIES THAT'S WHERE WE
TURN TO.
IT'S PART OF WHO WE ARE AS A
PEOPLE.
INNATELY WE HAVE A NEED TO REACH
OUT.
AND IT'S ONLY WHEN WE TRUST OUR
CREATOR.
AND THOSE WHO HAVE A
RELATIONSHIP WITH CHRIST OR
SENSE OF SPIRITUALITY, BUT AS I
COME FROM THE EVANGELICAL WORLD,
IT HELPS US PROCESS THIS GRIEF.
MEGYN: IT HELPS US LOOK OUT FOR
ONE ANOTHER.
YOU GO TO CHURCH JUST TO BIND
WITH THE COMMUNITY, TO HAVE THAT
SHARED EXPERIENCE.
IT COULD BE A CONCERT.
THE SHARED EXPERIENCE OF UP AND
DOWN AND TOGETHER AND BOND.
BUT WE NEED TO HAVE THAT BOND.
>> IT KEEPS US ACCOUNT BE AS
INDIVIDUALS.
IT KEEPS US CONNECT CANDIDATE AS
A COMMUNITY.
AND THAT'S WHY -- IT KEEPS US
CONNECTED AS A COMMUNITY.
WE SEE A CALLOUSNESS AND
COARSENESS OF OUR SOCIETY THAT
IS TROUBLING TO ALL OF US.
IF I WERE TO SAY RELIGION WOULD
SOLVE OUR PROBLEMS, RELATIONSHIP
WON'T SOLVE OUR PROBLEMS.
HAVING A RELATIONSHIP WITH
CHRIST, WITH THE JUDEO CHRISTIAN
WORLD VIEW, THAT MAKES SENSE FOR
US INDIVIDUALLY.
BUT AS A SOCIETY WE MOVED AWAY
FROM THAT.
AND IT IS IMPORTANT THAT WE
BRING THAT BACK IN AND NOT HE
CAN COLLUDE IT FROM THE PUBLIC
SQUARE.
IT IS -- AND NOT EXCLUDE IT FROM
THE PUBLIC SQUARE.
WHO KNOWS WHAT MOTIVATED THIS
GUY TO DO THIS.
BUT WE NEED TO BE LOOKING OUT
FOR OTHERS AND HAVING A MORAL
STANDARD OF WHAT'S ACCEPTABLE
AND WHAT'S NOT.
CLEARLY THIS IS NOT ACCEPTABLE.
BUT HOW DO WE PREVENT TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS FROM OCCURRING AGAIN?
MEGYN: A LOT OF PEOPLE GO TO
TEMPLE, THEY GO TO CHURCH ON A
DAY LIKE THIS AND LOOK TO
CONNECT WITH THEIR FELLOW HUMAN
BECOMES TO REMIND THEMSELVES WE
ARE HERE TOGETHER AND WE HAVE
THIS SHARED EXPERIENCE.
FOR SOME OF US THERE IS A HIGHER
POWER THAT WILL HELP US THROUGH
IT.
>> WE SHOULD ALL BE PRAYING FOR
THESE FAMILIES TODAY.
AS A FAVORIT -- AS A PARENT OF A
5-YEAR-OLD I CAN ONLY TELL YOU
MY HEART IS BROKEN FOR THEM.
MEGYN: WE ARE GOING TO TAKE A
QUICK BREAK.
WE'LL BE BACK IN MOMENT WITH
DR. KEITH ABLOW WHO EARLIER
SHARED THIS MESSAGE:THOSE WHO
LIVED THIS FIRSTHAND.
THE MOTHERS AND FAVORITES AND
BROTHERS AND SISTERS OF THOSE 18
CHILDREN.
I DON'T KNOW HOW YOU WOULD WAKE
UP TOMORROW AND HAVE YOUR
BREAKFAST AND FUNCTION IN THIS
WORLD.
>> THAT'S THE BEST THING, BY THE
WAY YOU CAN TELL THEM.
THAT'S WHAT I WOULD TELL THEM
THIS OFFICE.
I CANNOT FATHOM THE DEPTH OF
YOUR GRIEF.
I GIVE YOU CREDIT FOR YOUR
COURAGE.
I THINK SOMEWHERE OUT OF YOUR
INCREDIBLE WOUND COULD COME
EXTRAORDINARY SENSITIVITY SUCH
THAT YOU WOULD BE AN INCREDIBLE
GIFT TO OTHER PEOPLE IN LIFE.
YET I HESITATE TO ASK THAT OF
YOU KNOWING NOW HOW MUCH YOU ARE
SUFFERING.
YET I KNOW THAT'S POSSIBLE FOR
YOU.
BUT I DON'T PRETEND TO KNOW
EVERYTHING YOU ARE FEELING AND I
INVITE TO YOU TELL ME, PLEASE
TELL ME, BECAUSE SILENCE IS THE
ENEMY OF HEALING HERE.
[ Male Announcer ]
KIDS GROW UP IN NO TIME...
MARIE CALLENDER'S
TURKEY BREAST WITH STUFFING
IS A GREAT REASON TO SLOW DOWN.
CREAMY MASH POTATOES,
HOMESTYLE GRAVY
AND 320 CALORIES.
MARIE CALLENDER'S.
IT'S TIME TO SAVOR.
MEGYN: FOX NEWS ALERT.
YOU CAN SEE THE SCENE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT AS WE HAVE
REMAINED WITH THE NUMBER OF 26
DEAD.
277, INCLUDING THE GUNMAN.
-- 27, INCLUDING THE GUNMAN.
THERE ARE REPORTS FROM OTHER
NEWS OUTTHREATS NOT
INDEPENDENTLY CONFIRMED BY FOX
NEWS THAT THAT THE SHOOTER MAY
HAVE BEEN THE SON OF THE
KINDERGARTEN CLASS TEACHER.
WE ARE WORKING TO CONFIRM THAT.
PLEASE TAKE IT FOR WHAT IT'S
WORTH.
TWO NEWS OUTLETS CONFIRMING
THAT.
WE DID HEAR EARLIER THAT THE
BODY OF A WOMAN HAD BEEN FOUND
IN A HOUSE NEARBY THE SCHOOL AND
SHE MAY HAVE HAD TIES TO THE
SHOOTER.
WE WERE TOLD THE SHOOTER LIVED
IN HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY.
WE ARE DOING OUR BEST NOT TO GET
AHEAD OF OUR SKIS ON IT SO BEAR
WITH US.
KEN, THANKS FOR BEING HERE.
SOMETHING DIDN'T GO RIGHT HERE.
HOW CAN WE LEARN FROM IT?
>> AS YOU KNOW, AS A MOTHER, I
WAS STANDING ON THE PLAY GROUND
OF MY OWN CHILDREN'S SCHOOL
SUPERVISING ELEMENTARY KIDS AS
THIS STARTED BREAK AS A FAVORITE
VOLUNTEER.
WE KNOW AT ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
LEVELS VERY OFTEN WHEN WE SEE
VIOLENCE INCIDENTS ARISE,
SHOOTINGS OR ALTER CASES, THEY
COME FROM DOMESTIC SITUATIONS
BETWEEN PARENTS, NON-CUSTODIAL
PARENTS, OR SCHOOL EMPLOYEES.
SO AS THIS NEWS IS UNFOLDING
WHAT YOU JUST DESCRIBE COULD
POSSIBLY FIT SOME OF THE THINGS
WE HAVE SEEN IN THE PAST.
I WANT TO SAY FIRST MY PRAYERS
GOING OUT TO THE FAMILIES AS A
FATHER, THAT PARENTS NEED TO
ACROSS THE NATION ARE GOING TO
BE ASKING QUESTIONS AT THEIR
CHILDREN'S SCHOOL.
THEY ARE DOING SO NOW EVEN AT MY
OWN SCHOOL.
I JUST GOT A TEXT.
PARENTS NEED TO REMEMBER THEY
SHOULD BE SENDING THEIR KIDS TO
SCHOOL NEXT WEEK BECAUSE THIS IS
THE TIME WHERE SCHOOLS ACROSS
THE COUNTRY WILL BE SAFER
BECAUSE THIS IS THE FOREFRONT OF
OUR MINDS.
WHAT I WANT PARENTS TO KNOW IS
WE NEED TO TALK ABOUT SCHOOL
SAFETY IN THE WEEKS, MONTHS AND
YEARS AHEAD.
AS WE LOOKED A AT BUDGET CUTS AT
SCHOOL, FOCUS ON IMPORTANT
THINGS.
TEST SCORES, FINANCIAL ISSUES.
IT'S EASIER TO SCHOOL SAFETY TO
FALL TO THE BACK BURNER.
YOU HIT ON SOMETHING IMPORTANT
EARLIER WHEN YOU TALKED ABOUT OR
ALLUDED TO TRAINING OUR STAFF.
WE COULD HAVE THE LOCKS ON THE
DOORS, THE BUZZERS, THE
INTERCOMS.
WE HAVE TO TRAIN OUR SCHOOL
EMPLOYEES.
WE HAVE TO TRAIN OUR PARENTS NOT
TO PIGGY BACK IN WHEN SOMEONE
AHEAD OF THEM GOES IN THE DOOR.
WE NEED TO TALK ABOUT SITUATIONS
IN OUR FAMILIES AND SHARE THOSE
AS SCHOOL EMPLOYEES WITH OUR
EMPLOYERS IF THERE IS A RISK AND
WE NEED TO BE WORKING WITH
AGE-APPROPRIATE LEVELS WITH KIDS
TO HAVE DRILLS.
WE DON'T NEED TO TEACH
KINDERGARTEN KIDS TO ATTACK
ARMED INTRUDERS AND THROW
PENCILS AT THEM AND I DON'T
THINK WE NEED A METAL DETECTOR
AT EVERY DOOR.
BUT WE NEED ALERT STAFF.
WE NEED TO DO OUR TRAINING.
MEGYN: I WAS TALKING ABOUT THIS
EARLIER WITH BOB TSTRANG.
SHOULD PARENTS THINK ABOUT
POOLING THEIR RESOURCES TO PAY
FOR ARMED SECURITY GUARDS?
DO WE NEED THEM AT SCHOOLS TO
PROTECT OUR KIDS?
IF AN ARMED SECURITY GUARD HAD
BEEN ON SITE COULD THIS MAN HAVE
UNLEASHED THE TYPE OF DAMAGE HE
DID?
>> WE HAVE SCHOOL-BASED POLICE
OFFICERS.
THERE IS SOME CIVIL RIGHTS AND
SPECIAL INTEREST GROUPS HAVE
JUST THIS WEEK BEEN BEFORE
CONGRESS COMPLAINING ABOUT
POLICE OFFICERS IN SCHOOLS.
AND I THINK THAT WE NEED TO
REALLY TAKE A LOOK AT THE ROLE
OF THE OFFICER.
I SUPPORT HAVING SCHOOL-BASED
OFFICERS.
MEGYN: MY APOLOGIES.
BREAKING NEWS OUTSIDE OF THE
HOSPITAL.
>> THEY GAVE LIMITED
INFORMATION.
THEY WERE TALKING ABOUT THREE
PATIENTS WHO WERE BROUGHT HERE.
BUT THEY WOULD NOT GO INTO
PARTICULARS ABOUT WHO THESE
PEOPLE ARE.
WHETHER THEY ARE MALE OR FEMALE,
CHILDREN OR ADULT.
THEY WOULDN'T SAY ANYTHING
WHATSOEVER.
THEY SAIDER IN THE PROCESS OF
NOTIFYING THE FAMILIES.
AND MAYBE THEY WOULD END UP
HAVING A NEWS CONFERENCE IN THE
NEXT HALF-HOUR TO AN HOUR OR SO.
AT THAT POINT THEY ARE STILL NOT
SAYING WHETHER THEY ARE GOING TO
BE GIVING US ANY MORE
INFORMATION AS FAR AS THE
PARTICULARS OF THESE PEOPLE.
HOWEVER, WE DID HEAR THAT WHO
THESE THREE PEOPLE ARE.
ONE IS A TEACHER WHO WAS SHOT
EITHER IN THE FOOT OR THE LEG.
AND THE OTHER TWO ARE CHILDREN.
WE WERE TOLD OR WE ARE HEARING
THAT THOSE INJURIES ARE NOT
LIFE-THREATENING.
WHICH IS SO GOOD, THAT'S SUCH
GOOD NEWS TO HEAR ABOUT THESE
THREE PEOPLE CONSIDERING THE
TRAGEDY THAT THIS TOWN AND ALL
OF THESE POOR FAMILIES ARE
DEALING WITH.
WE HAVE CAMERAS SET UP HERE.
YOU HAVE THE LOCAL REPORTERS IN
CONNECTICUT AS WELL AS REPORTERS
FROM NEW YORK WHO CAME UP.
YOU CAN SEE ALL THE CAMERAS
LINED UP THERE WAITING TO SEE
WHETHER THERE WILL BE A NEWS
CONFERENCE.
THE LOCATION WHERE THEY HAVE
US -- WE ARE ON THE CAMPUS OF
THE HOSPITAL BUT WE ARE AT THE
MEDICAL ARTS CENTER.
MEGYN: THE THREE VICTIMS -- WE
WERE TOLD THREE VICTIMS WERE
TAKEN TO THE HOSPITAL IN
CONNECTICUT.
WE HAD PRECIOUS LITTLE
INFORMATION ON THEM.
NOW, YOU HEARD IT FROM OUR WNYW
AFFILIATE REPORTER THAT THEY ARE
BELIEVED TO BE IN A POSITION TO
RECOVER.
THEIR WOUND ARE NOT
LIFE-THREATENING.
THAT'S A BIG RELIEF IN A DAY OF
UNSPEAKABLE TRAGEDY.
KEN, YOU WERE TOUCHING ON THE
ISSUE OF ARMED GUARDS IN SCHOOL
AND YOU A RAISE AN INTERESTING
ISSUE.
SOME PEOPLE HAVE A REAL
OBJECTION TO THAT.
I SUPPOSE THE THOUGHT IS DO WE
WANT TO HAVE SOMEBODY WITH A
LOADED GUN WALKING AROUND OUR
SCHOOL CAMPUSES WHEN IT MAY NOT
BE NECESSARY.
WHEN THANK GOD IN 99% OF
CIRCUMSTANCES IT'S NEVER
NECESSARY.
>> ONE OF THE THINGS WE WORK
HARD AT IN TRAINING SCHOOLS IS
TO HAVE A RELATIONSHIP WITH
THEIR LOCAL LAW ENFORCEMENT.
THERE ARE MANY SCHOOL POLICE
OFFICERS ASSIGNED FROM LOCAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT COUNTY SHERIFF'S
DETECTIVES.
STATE POLICE OFFICERS, IN SOME
CASES LOCAL POLICE, WHO DO WORK
IN OUR SCHOOLS AND MOST OF THEM
PERFORM A PREVENTATIVE ROLE.
THEY BUILD RELATIONSHIPS WITH
KIDS.
THEY FIND OUT ABOUT THESE ISSUES
THAT START AT HOME.
THINGS THAT MAY SPILL OVER INTO
THE SCHOOL.
I THINK THAT ONE TOOL.
TRYING TO LOGISTICALLY PUT AN
OFFICER IN EVERY ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL WOULD BE AN
IMPLEMENTATION CHALLENGE,
FINANCIAL CHALLENGE AND I'M NOT
SURE IF IT'S SOMETHING WE WOULD
BE ABLE TO DO IN THE SHORT TERM.
THE FIRST AND BEST LINE OF
DEFENSE IS A WELL-TRAINED HIGHLY
ALERT SCHOOL STAFF AND STUDENT
BODY WHO HAS RELATIONSHIPS WITH
THEIR MENTAL HEALTH, POLICE AND
COMMUNITY SPONSORS.
WE NEED MENTAL DETECTORS.
WE HAVE PEOPLE WITH MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES.
IT'S NOT SOME REAL THING YOU CAN
GET YOUR HAND ON THAT'S
CONCRETE.
WE DON'T DEAL WITH THAT WELL IN
OUR SOCIETY.
MEGYN: IF THE LAST FEW YEARS
HAVEN'T PROVED THAT, I DON'T
KNOW WHAT THEY PROVED.
>> I HAVE BEEN IN THIS BUSINESS
25 YEARS AND I HAVE A VERY
STRANGE FEELING AS I SIT HERE
TALK WITH YOU TODAY.
AS A FAVORITE, SEND YOUR KIDS TO
SCHOOL, TALK WITH YOUR SCHOOL
OFFICIALS, DON'T PANIC.
FIND OUT WHAT THEY ARE DOING.
SEE HOW YOU CAN SUPPORT.
GO OUT ON THE PLAYGROUND IF YOU
CAN AND HELP SUPERVISE.
THAT'S WORTH A MILLION DOLLARS.
MEGYN: I WANT TO GET TO TRACE
GALLAGHER.
WE HAVE BREAKING NEWS ON THE
SHOOTER AND HIS MOTHER.
>> Reporter: THE INFORMATION
WE HAVE IS THERE IS A
POSSIBILITY THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER
MAY HAVE BEEN A TEACHER AT THE
SCHOOL.
BUT THEN WE WENT ONTO THE WEB
SITE OF THE SCHOOL AND THE TWO
KINDERGARTEN TEACHERS DON'T
SOUNDS LIKE IT WOULD BE THE
MOTHER.
THESE ARE REPORTS COMING OUT OF
THERE.
WE HAVE NOT CONFIRMED THEM.
THERE IS A POSSIBILITY THE
MOTHER WORKED AT THE SCHOOL.
GOING ON TO KIND OF AS WE SCAN
THIS, RYAN LANZA LIVED IN
HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY.
HE WENT TO HIGH SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
HIS MOM LIVED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT AND APPARENTLY HAD
SOME CONNECTION TO THE SCHOOL.
HE WAS A GRADUATE OF NEWTOWN
HIGH SCHOOL.
AND POLICE CONFIRMED THERE WAS A
BODY FOUND IN THERE.
AND IT IS A VERY STRONG
POSSIBILITY THE BODY WAS THE
SHOOTER'S MOTHER.
WE ARE NOW TRYING TO GET MORE
INFORMATION ABOUT WHAT HE DID
FOR WORK.
MEGYN: JUST TO JUMP IN.
OUR JUSTICE DEPARTMENT SOURCES
ARE TELLING US THAT RYAN LANZA'S
MOTHER NANCY IS PRESUMED DEAD.
THAT'S WHAT WE ARE BEING TOLD.
HIS MOTHER IS BEING PRESUMED
DEAD.
THAT SHE DID WORK AT THAT SCHOOL
WHERE THE SHOOTING TOOK PLACE.
BUT IT'S UNCLEAR IF SHE WAS
KILLED IN THE SCHOOL OR AT HER
HOME.
ALSO BEING TOLD HIS PARENTS WERE
DIVORCED.
IT'S POSSIBLE THE MOTHER LIVED
IN CONNECTICUT, THE FATHER IN
NEW JERSEY.
SHE IS PRESUMED DEAD.
THEY DON'T KNOW IF SHE WAS
KILLED IN THE SCHOOL OR HER
HOME.
IT EARLIER INFORMATION WAS THEY
FOUND A BODY IN THE HOME NEAR
THE SCHOOL.
>> Reporter: THAT'S THE
INFORMATION WE HAVE.
THERE WAS A BODY FOUND INSIDE
THE HOME BELONG TOGETHER MOTHER
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT AND SHE
WORKED FOR THE SCHOOL.
AND THE REPORT WENT ON TO SAY
THE BELIEF WAS THAT HE TARGETED
THE MOTHER FIRST, THEN WENT AND
WAS TARGETING THE STUDENTS AT
THE SCHOOL.
REMEMBER IF YOU LOOK AT THE
CHAIN OF EVENTS.
HE WAS LET THROUGH THE DOOR
SOMETIME BETWEEN 9:30 AND 9:40.
WENT TO THE AD MIN STRAY TOUGH
OFFICE AND OPENED FIRE DURING
THE MORNING ANNOUNCEMENTS AND
ATTACKED THE PRINCIPAL AND VICE
PRINCIPAL AND PSYCHOLOGIST.
THE NURSE WAS IN THERE.
WHILE THE MORNING ANNOUNCEMENTS
WERE BEING MADE THE REST OF THE
SCHOOL COULD HEAR THE VIOLENCE
AND GUNFIRE OVER THE SCHOOL
INTERCOM.
AT THAT POINT APPARENTLY WENT TO
A CLASSROOM.
WE KNOW A KINDERGARTEN CLASS IS
UNACCOUNTED FOR.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT CLASSROOM HE
WENT TO.
BUT HE APPARENTLY WENT TO A
CLASSROOM AND SHOT AND KILLED 18
KID.
THE INFORMATION WE ARE GETTING
IS HE APPARENTLY WAS GOING TO
THE SCHOOL TO TARGET THE KIDS TO
BEGIN WITH.
WHETHER THESE WERE HER STUDENTS
OR FORMER STUDENTS, STILL HAVE
MUCH UNCONFIRMED.
BUT WE ARE WORKING TO FIND OUT
MUCH MORE INFORMATION ABOUT
24-YEAR-OLD RYAN LANZA.
MEGYN: MOMENT AFTER WE REPORTED
FROM THE JUSTICE DEPARTMENT AND
THE "NEW YORK TIMES," ALSO
REPORTING NOW THAT THE ALLEGED
SCHOOL GUNMAN KILLED HIS MOTHER
WHO WAS A TEACHER AT THE SCHOOL
ALONG WITH STUDENT AND OTHERS.
THE STORY DOES APPEAR TO BE
GETTING MORE CLEAR AT THIS HOUR.
THOUGH UNDERSTANDING IT REMAINS
IMPOSSIBLE.
WE ARE ALSO JUST GETTING
COMMENTS FROM A FATHER ON THE
SCENE WHO SPOKE ABOUT THE HORROR
THAT ANY PARENT WOULD FEEL UPON
HEARING THEIR CHILD'S SCHOOL HAS
BEEN TARGETED BY A GUNMAN.
>> THERE IS NO WORDS IT'S SHEER
TERROR, AND A SENSE OF IMMEDIATE
URGENCY, AND, YOU KNOW, TO GET
TO YOUR CHILD AND TO BE INTO
PROTECT THEM.
BECAUSE THAT'S THE IMMEDIATE
THING.
IS MY CHILD HURT?
THEY ARE ALONE, THEY ARE NOT
WITH ME.
HOW DO I GET TO THEM.
MEGYN: THE PARENTS WERE OUT
THERE.
YOU CAN IMAGINE THE PANIC.
THE FULL-BODY PANIC.
YOU CAN SEE TONIGHT SOME OF THE
PICTURES.
THERE WAS ONE MOTHER I SAW
EARLIER, YOU COULD SEE HER
RINGING HER HANDS -- YOU COULD
SEE HER RINGING HER HANDS.
THERE HAS TO BE A GUILING
FEELING AS WELL.
FORGIVE ME I'M HEARING
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL MAKE ON
CAMERA COMMENTS ON THIS COMING
UP MOMENTARILY.
I BELIEVE JUST AFTER 3:00 P.M.
EASTERN TIME THE PRESIDENT WILL
SPEAK TO THIS INCREDIBLY AWFUL
SCHOOL SHOOTING IN CONNECTICUT
THAT BEGAN TODAY.
WE WERE HOPING THERE WERE
INITIAL REPORTS ON ANOTHER
CHANNEL THAT NO CHILDREN WERE
INJURED.
NO REPORTS OF CHILDREN INJURED
IT READ.
NOW WE KNOW THE TRUTH IS VERY,
VERY DIFFERENT.
WANT TO GET BACK TO DR. KIET
ABLOW.
-- DR. KEITH ABLOW.
THOSE DUAL FEELINGS OF THANK GOD
IT WASN'T MY CHILD, THEN THE
AWFUL GUILT OR I DON'T KNOW WHAT
THE WORLD IS WHEN YOU REALIZE
YOU ARE FEELING HE LATE AS OTHER
PARENTS ARE MOURNING THE DEATH
OF THEIR 5-YEAR-OLD WHO DIED AT
AT HAND OF A GUNMAN WHO GUNNED
THEM DOWN LIKE THEY WERE
NOTHING.
>> THE RAN DOCUMENT AND CRUEL
NATURE OF THIS KIND OF ACT
COMPLICATES THINGS
PSYCHOLOGICALLY EVEN FOR THE
SURVIVORS WHO WILL NEED HELP
LATER ON TO TRY TO PUT THIS IN
SOME KIND OF PERSPECTIVE.
BECAUSE I WORKED WITH PEOPLE
AGAIN AND AGAIN FOR WHOM EITHER
HAVING A TRAGEDY VISIT OR HAVING
SURVIVED SIT, WHEN A SIBLING IS
STRICKEN WITH CANCER.
HAVING NOT BEEN THE ONE TO GET
SICK LEADS THEM TO FEEL UNSAFE.
THE RANDOMNESS OF IT.
UNFAIRNESS OF IT.
THE FACT THAT IS THERE NOT A LOT
YOU AS AN INDIVIDUAL CAN DO TO
PROTECT YOURSELF FROM IT MAKES
PEOPLE VISIT THEIR OWN MORTALITY
AND THAT FINE THREAD FROM WHICH
WE ALL HANG.
EARLIER THAN YOU HAD HOPED.
HASN'T WHAT THESE KIDS ARE
CONTENDING WITH.
THESE WILL BE FOREVER SPECIAL
CHILDREN PERHAPS, CAPABLE OF
EXTRAORDINARY BRAVERY OR EMA ANY
BUT ALSO VULNERABLE IN A SPECIAL
WAY.
MEGYN: YOUR THOUGHTS ON WHAT WE
ARE HEAR BEING THIS ACT PAT WE
BELIEVE THIS GUNMAN KILLED HIS
MOTHER.
WE BELIEVE IN THE HOUSE OUTSIDE
OF THE SCHOOL.
AND IT APPEARS HE MAY HAVE
KILLED HIS MOTHER WHO ARE WAS A
TEACHER IN THIS SCHOOL.
>> MY THOUGHTS ARE THIS.
AS MORE FACTS COME IN, THIS WILL
LIKELY BE ANOTHER STORY WHERE
YOU SAY, WELL, THE UNTHINKABLE
AND INEXPLICABLE NOW IS
FATHOMABLE.
WE CAN SEE THE TRAIN COMING DOWN
THE TRACKS.
THE AWFUL COLLISION COMING AND
SADLY SPECTATORS BY THE RAILWAY
WHO FELT DISEMPOWERED OR DIDN'T
FILE WAS THEIR PLACE TO
INTERVENE OR EVEN A THERAPIST
WHO DIDN'T THINK IT WAS TIME TO
PULL THE TRIGGER AND HOSPITALIZE
THIS PERSON, I THINK RIGHT NOW
THIS CAN BE SADLY A LABORATORY
WHERE WE LOOK AND SAY WHAT COULD
HAVE BEEN DONE.
IF IT'S NOTHING, FINE.
BUT IT IS LIKELY THERE WILL BE
THINGS THAT COULD HAVE BEEN
DONE.
I CAN'T TELL YOU HOW MANY OF MY
COLLEAGUES -- I DON'T MEAN TO
CALL ANYBODY OUT HERE -- BUT IN
THE MENTAL HEALTHCARE SYSTEM I
SOMETIMES MAKE STRANGE CALLS TO
E.R.s WHERE I WILL SAY YOU
HAVE GOT TO HOSPITALIZE THIS
PERSON HE WAS IN MY OFFICE AN
SAYS HE WANTS TO KILL SOMEBODY.
YOU WILL HEAR BACK FROM A
CLINICIAN, WELL, HE'S NOT SAYING
THAT NOW.
I SAID NOW HE'S IN THE E.R. AND
HE'S SAYING THAT TO LEAVE.
THEY SAY HE'S CONTRACTING FOR
SAFETY AND THE INSURANCE COMPANY
SAYS THEY WON'T PAY NOW.
SO WE HAVE SO MUCH FIXING TO DO.
MEGYN: WHAT'S IT GOING TO TAKE?
32 DEAD AT VIRGINIA TECH JUST A
COUPLE YEARS AGO AND WE DIDN'T
REVAMP' THE MENTAL HEALTH
SYSTEM.
NOW YOU HAVE 18 DEAD KIDS.
IS THIS ENOUGH?
>> I DON'T KNOW IF IT'S ENOUGH
BECAUSE THERE IS SO MUCH STIGMA
ATTACHED TO THE MENTAL
HEALTHCARE SYSTEM.
THERE IS SO MUCH RECEIPT SENSE H
RETISCENCE.
WE HAVE SOME TO EMPOWER PEOPLE
TO GIVE TREATMENT TO THOSE TO
DON'T WANT TREATMENT.
MEGYN: FOX NEWS CONFIRMING RYAN
LANZA, THAT HIS FATHER WAS ALSO
KILLED IN HIS HOME IN NEW
JERSEY.
THIS IS IN ADDITION TO HIS
MOTHER BEING FOUND DEAD IN
CONNECTICUT.
>> THESE STORIES IN MY
EXPERIENCE AS A FORENSIC
PSYCHIATRIST, THE STRANGERS WHO
PAY THE TOLL ARE PAYING IT FOR
INTENSELY PERSONAL DRAMAS.
CONNECTED USUALLY TO INCREDIBLY
INTENSE PSYCHOLOGICAL CONFLICTS
BETWEEN INDIVIDUALS WHO ARE VERY
CLOSE TO EACH OTHER.
WE SEE IT AGAIN AND AGAIN.
PEOPLE KILL BECAUSE THERE IS A
SPOUSE AT SODS WITH HIS WIFE
WHO -- SPOUSE AT ODDS WITH HIS
WIFE.
MEGYN: I KNOW YOU CAN'T ANSWER
THIS BUT I HAVE TO TRY.
I THINK WE ARE ALL TRYING.
THEN WHAT MAKES YOU KILL A
KINDERGARTEN FULL OF BABIES.
>> THE TERRIBLE SENSE THAT YOU
ARE DISEMPOWERED AND YOU ARE
SPIRITUALLY DEAD MAKES YOU
CREATE IN THE WORLD AN AWFUL
CANVAS REPRESENTING YOUR
INTERIOR WORLD.
THAT'S NOT ALWAYS THE CASE, BUT
THAT IS ONE WAY TO SEE THIS.
THAT YOU PROJECT THE FRAGMENTED
NATURE OF YOUR INTERNAL WORLD.
THE FACT THAT YOU FEEL
DECIMATED.
YOU CREATE A SYMBOL OF THAT.
AN AWFUL, TERRIBLE MONSTROUS
SYMBOL OF IT THAT THIS WILL BE
YOUR LEGACY.
THAT YOU HAVE FINALLY SPOKEN AND
SHOWN EVERYONE WHAT YOU HAVE
BEEN FEELING INSIDE.
THAT'S THE TERRIBLE, AWFUL
TRUTH.
MEGYN: THE SHOOTER IS 24 YEARS
OLD.
THE SHOOTER AT THE MALL SHOOTING
IN OREGON WAS 22 YEARS OLD.
THESE ARE YOUNG GUYS.
YOU MENTIONED HOW PEOPLE LOSE
THEMSELVES IN CERTAIN ONLINE
ACTIVITY, GAME, WHAT HAVE YOU.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THE BACKGROUND
WAS WITH THESE GUYS.
BUT IT DOESN'T SEEM TOTALLY
COINCIDENTALLY THAT THEY ARE
BOTH IN THEIR YOUNG 20s AND
YOUNG MEN.
>> I THINK WE HAVE TO LOOK AT
THE FORCES THAT EMPOWER PEOPLE
TO GET SOME KNOWLEDGE THROUGH
THE INTERNET.
BUT THERE ARE A LOT OF
DEHUMANIZING FORCES THAT COME
WITH THAT.
REALITY TV IS NO FRIEND OF
PREVENTING SUCH THINGS.
FACEBOOK IS NO FRIEND OF
PREVENTING SUCH THINGS I HAVE TO
SAY.
AND I THINK WE ARE AT A TIME
AGAIN AND WE MENTIONED THIS
EARLIER.
WE PUSHED THE RED LINE OF THE
UNTHINKABLE INTO KINDERGARTEN
CLASSROOMS.
WE HAVE GOT TO DIAL IT BACK.
WE HAVE GOT TO SHOW A BIG
RESPONSE HERE OF GRIEF, EMPATHY,
OUTREACH TO BALANCE THE
MONSTROUSITY OF THIS.
THAT'S SOME KIND OF INSULATION
AGAINST SOMEONE SAYING I THINK
THAT MY FORUM.
THAT'S WHERE I'M GOING TO
EXPRESS MYSELF.
HOW FRACTURED I FEEL IS GOING TO
BE SEEN IN THE BLOOD ON THE
FLOOR OF THIS CLASSROOM.
MEGYN: THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
HELPING US.
WE APPRECIATE YOU BEING HERE.
I WANT TO BRING YOU THIS SAD
UPDATE AS WELL.
THE NUMBER OF CHILDREN KILLED
HAS NOW BEEN INCREASED TO 20.
20 CHILDREN DEAD.
FIVE ADULT DEAD AND THE SHORT.
26 DEAD, 20 OF THEM CHILDREN.
THE LAW ENFORCEMENT COMMUNITY
HAS NOT INDEPENDENTLY CONFIRMED
THESE ARE KINDERGARTENERS.
THAT IS OUR BELIEF BASED OTHER
REPORTING.
ONE FATHER SAID HIS ON WAS IN
CLASS WHEN THE GUNMAN BURST IN
AND SHOT THE TEACHER.
HE GRABBED A BUNCH OF OF HIS
FRIEND AND RAN.
THE SHOOTER DID NOT SAY A WORD.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL SPEAK TO
THE NATION AT 3:15 P.M. EASTERN
TIME.
WE APPRECIATE YOU BEING WITH US
ON THIS IMPORTANT NEWS DAY.
WE'LL GET THROUGH IT TOGETHER.
THEN WE'LL FIGURE IT OUT
TOGETHER.
BUT OUR COVERAGE CONTINUES NOW
WITH "STUDIO B."
>> THERE IS NO WORDS IT OF THE
SHEER TERROR AND SENSE OF
IMMEDIATE URGENCY AND TO GET TO
YOUR CHILD AND TO BE THERE TO
PROTECT THEM.
THAT WHAT YOU WANT -- THAT'S THE
IMMEDIATE THING, IS MY CHILD
HURT.
YOU KNOW, THEY ARE ALONE, THEY
ARE NOT WITH ME.
YOU KNOW, HOW DO I GET TO THEM.
ANNCR: Some politicians seem to
think Medicare and...
Social Security are just numbers
in a budget.
Well, we worked hard for those
benefits.
We earned them.
And if Washington tries to cram
decisions about the future...
of these programs into a last
minute budget deal...
we'll all pay the price.
AARP is fighting to protect
seniors with responsible...
solutions that strengthen
Medicare and...
Social Security for generations
to come.
We can do better than a last
minute deal...
that would hurt all of us.
PROGRESSIVE DIRECT AND OTHER
CAR INSURANCE COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
CALL OR CLICK TODAY.
AND I'M HERE TO TELL HOMEOWNERS
THAT ARE 62 AND OLDER
ABOUT A GREAT WAY
TO LIVE A BETTER RETIREMENT.
IT'S CALLED A REVERSE MORTGAGE.
[ Male Announcer ]
CALL RIGHT NOW
TO RECEIVE YOUR FREE
DVD AND BOOKLET
WITH NO
OBLIGATION.
IT ANSWERS QUESTIONS LIKE
HOW A REVERSE MORTGAGE WORKS,
HOW MUCH YOU QUALIFY FOR,
THE WAYS TO RECEIVE YOUR MONEY,
AND MORE.
PLUS, WHEN
YOU CALL NOW,