>> Steve: BEFORE WE LEAVE YOU
TODAY, WE'VE GOT TO THANK
MARLENEA FOR THE DECORATIONS.
WE GOT THE CHRISTMAS DECORATIONS
FOR A WEEK.
THEY'VE BEEN FANTASTIC.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> Brian: IT'S THE BEST WE'VE
EVER HAD.
IF YOU HAVE TO RUN FROM THE TV,
RUN TO THE RADIO.
WE HAVE A LOT OF EXCITING GUESTS
COMING YOUR WAY.
>> Steve: A BIG SHOW FOR YOU.
>> Gretchen: "FOX & FRIENDS"
CHRISTMAS PARTY PICKS MONDAY.
THAT SHOW TODAY.
GOOD MORNING, EVERYBODY ON A
BOWING OUT U.N. AMBASSADOR
SUSAN RICE IS OUT OF THE
RUNNING AS SECRETARY OF
STATE.
MANY QUESTIONS REMAIN ON THE
RESPONSE TO TERROR ATTACKS
IN BENGHAZI.
SOME WONDER WHETHER OR NOT
WE'LL LEARN THE TRUTH.
GOOD MORNING, EVERYBODY.
I'M BILL HEMMER.
WELCOME TO "AMERICA'S
NEWSROOM." WE HAVE OUR NICE
LITTLE "ELF" HERE TODAY.
>> I'M ALISYN CAMEROTA IN
FOR MARTHA TODAY.
SHE WANTS TO AVOID A VOTE,
LENGTH I, DISRUPTIVE AND
COSTLY CONFIRMATION PROCESS.
CRITICS SAY REGARDLESS OF
RYCE'S DECISION THE
INVESTIGATION INTO BENGHAZI
WILL CONTINUE.
HERE IS LINDSEY GRAHAM ON
THAT.
>> I HOLD HER ACCOUNTABLE
AND RESPONSIBLE FOR
MISLEADING THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE.
FAILURES ON THE INTELLIGENCE
COMMUNITY.
THERE IS FOG OF WAR
COMPONENT.
I THINK SHE WAS CHOSEN FOR A
REASON
BILL: STILL MORE ON THAT
STATEMENT NOW WITH BUY ON
YORK, CHIEF POLITICAL
CORRESPONDENT FOR THE
"WASHINGTON EXAMINER".
GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
SO MANY QUESTIONS REMAIN.
FIRST OFF WHY DID THEY MAKE
THIS MOVE NOW?
>> BECAUSE TIME WAS RUNNING
OUT AND THE ADMINISTRATION,
I THINK, HOPED THAT
OPPOSITION AMONG REPUBLICANS
IN THE SENATE TO RICE WOULD
DIMINISH BUT IT DIDN'T.
THE THING THAT REALLY KILLED
IT, THEY UNDERSTOOD, JOHN
McCAIN, LINDSEY GRAHAM,
KELLY AYOTTE OPPOSED HER.
THE THING THAT KILLED IT
WHEN SHE MET SUSAN COLLINS
WHO INTRODUCED HER AT HER
CONFIRMATION HEARING AND
BEEN A RISE SUPPORTER AND
SAID THERE WERE SERIOUS
QUESTIONS ABOUT THE
NOMINATION.
AT THAT POINT THE
HANDWRITING WAS ON THE WALL.
BILL: SHE IS CONSIDERED A
MODERATE, IF YOU HAVE A GOOD
CHANCE OF GETTING THROUGH
THAT WOULD BE THE SIGN YOU
HAVE A CHANCE BUT WHAT
GRAHAM JUST SAID, SHE WAS
THE MOST POLITICALLY
COMPLIANT PERSON THEY COULD
FIND, THAT'S LOADED.
>> WELL I MEAN THIS GOES
BACK TO WHAT SHE SAID IN THE
AFTERMATH OF THOSE BENGHAZI
ATTACKS WHEN SHE SAID IT
WASN'T A TERRORIST ACT.
IT WAS THE RESULT OF
SPONTANEOUS PROTESTS AGAINST
THAT ISLAMIC VIDEO.
WE KNOW THAT SUSAN RICE WAS
PICKED IN PART BECAUSE OF
HER INTENSE LOYALTY TO
PRESIDENT OBAMA.
NOT LIKE SHE IS THE
BEST-LOVED PERSON IN
WASHINGTON.
IT IS THE FACT SHE HAS BEEN
WITH THE PRESIDENT FOR QUITE
A WHILE.
SHE WAS A CLINTON PERSON AND
WENT WITH OBAMA EARLY IN
2006 AND 2007.
THERE IS A LOT OF LOYALTY
THERE AND THE PRESIDENT
COULD COUNT ON HER.
BILL: WITHIN A WEEK, YOU
WERE FIVE DAYS WHEN YOU SAW
SUSAN RICE IN THE FOLLOWING
IMAGE.
FIVE DIFFERENT SUNDAY TALK
SHOWS ON EVERY NETWORK ON
THAT SUNDAY.
NOW HERE IS PART OF THE
INTERVIEW ON "FOX NEWS
SUNDAY" WHERECHRIS WALLACE
STARTED ALL OF THIS TOO,
LISTEN.
>> WHAT HAPPENED INITIALLY
IT WAS A SPONTANEOUS
REACTION TO WHAT HAD JUST
TRANSPIRED IN CAIRO.
AS A CONSEQUENCE OF THE
VIDEO.
PEOPLE GATHERED OUTSIDE THE
EMBASSY AND THEN IT GREW
VERY VIOLENT.
BILL: AS A CONSEQUENCE OF
THE VIDEO.
DO WE GET TO THE BOTTOM OF
BENGHAZI NOW?
>> WELL, REPUBLICANS ARE
CERTAINLY GOING TO KEEP
TRYING.
HILLARY CLINTON WHO HAD A
MUCH BIGGER ROLE IN ALL THIS,
WILL TESTIFY BEFORE THE
HOUSE AND THE SENATE SOON
BUT I TELL YOU THEY'RE VERY
FRUSTRATED.
REPRESENTATIVE JASON
CHAFFETZ WHO IS HELPING LEAD
THIS INVESTIGATION IN THE
HOUSE, WANTS TO TALK TO A
LOT OF PEOPLE WHO WERE
SURVIVORS OF THIS ATTACK.
IT IS NOT JUST THAT
AMBASSADOR STEVENS AND THREE
OTHERS WERE KILLED, SEVERAL
OTHERS WERE INJURED AND THEY
HAVE INFORMATION.
HE CAN NOT GET IN CONTACT
WITH THEM.
THERE IS LOT OF CONFLICT
BETWEEN REPUBLICANS ON THE
HILL AND THE ADMINISTRATION
THAT HAS NOT BEEN RESOLVED.
BILL: THAT IS AN INTERESTING
POINT.
ALL THE PEOPLE HAVE A STORY.
THE QUESTION IS WHETHER OR
NOT WE HEAR IS PUBLICLY.
BYRON YORK, THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU, BILL.
BILL: ALISYN.
ALISYN: AMBASSADOR RICE IS
EXPECTED TO MEET WITH THE
PRESIDENT PRIVATELY TODAY.
THE PRESIDENT HAS BEEN VOCAL
FOR HER AND BLASTING
REPUBLICAN CRITICS FOR WHAT
HE CALLS UNFAIR AND
MISLEADING ATTACKS ON RICE.
BILL: MORE AMERICANS WANT TO
SEE SENATOR JOHN KERRY
NOMINATED AS THE NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE MORE THAN
AMBASSADOR RICE EVEN BEFORE
SHE TOOK HER NAME OUT OF
PUBLIC CONTENTION.
THE LATEST FOX POLLING
SHOWING 23% SUPPORTING
SENATOR KERRY, 19% WENT FOR
AMBASSADOR RICE.
37% SAID THEY WANT TO SEE
SOMEONE ELSE IN THAT JOB.
18% SAYING NOT SO SURE.
ALISYN: INTERESTING TO SEE
WHAT EVERYONE SAYS DURING
THESE TWO HOURS.
THERE ARE NOW CONFLICTING
REPORTS WHETHER SECRETARY OF
STATE HILLARY CLINTON WILL
ACTUALLY TESTIFY TO A HOUSE
COMMITTEE ON THE LIBYAN
ATTACKS.
WE REPORTED TO YOU THAT
CLINTON WAS EXPECTED TO FACE
THE HOUSE FOREIGN AFFAIRS
COMMITTEE NEXT WEEK.
NOW THE STATE DEPARTMENT IS
SAYING NOT SO FAST.
IN JUST A COUPLE MINUTES
WE'LL SPEAK TO CONGRESSMAN
ED ROYCE FROM THE FOREIGN
AFFAIRS COMMITTEE TO SEE
WHAT HE THINKS ABOUT ALL
THIS.
BILL: WHAT DO YOUING THIS
WEEKEND, HUH?
WHAT IS JOHN BOEHNER DOING
THIS WEEKEND?
THE SPEAKER OF THE HOUSE AND
PRESIDENT OBAMA MET
FACE-TO-FACE FOR A 50 MINUTE
MEETING LATE YESTERDAY
AFTERNOON.
THE TWO MEN SPOKE FOR ABOUT
AN HOUR.
AS SPEAKER BOEHNER LEFT THE
CAPITOL HE SAID, QUOTE,
WE'RE DOING GREAT.
BEFORE THAT MEETING THE
PRESIDENT DID A ROUND OF
LOCAL TV INTERVIEWS AND TOLD
A REPORTER THE FOLLOWING.
LISTEN HERE.
>> THE BIG PROBLEM RIGHT NOW
IS THAT REPUBLICANS IN THE
HOUSE ARE RESISTANT TO THE
IDEA OF THE WEALTHIEST
AMERICANS PAYING HIGHER TAX
RATES AND I UNDERSTAND THEY
HAVE A PHILOSOPHICAL
OBJECTION.
ON THE OTHER HAND, YOU KNOW,
WE'RE WILLING TO MAKE SOME
REALLY TOUGH DECISIONS ABOUT
SPENDING CUTS.
BILL: WELL, IT'S BOEHNER
PLAN FOR THE WEEKEND MAYBE
THE REAL SIGN OF ANY
PROGRESS.
WE'LL TELL YOU WHAT HE IS
DOING AND TALK TO "FOX NEWS
SUNDAY" ANCHOR CHRIS WALLACE
ON THAT COMING UP A BIT
LATER THIS MORNING.
ALISYN: FOX NEWS ALERT FOR
YOU NOW BECAUSE DEFENSE
SECRETARY LEON PANETTA
ANNOUNCING THAT THE U.S. IS
SENDING PATRIOT MISSILES AND
TROOPS TO TURKEY TO DEAL
WITH THE GROWING THREAT FROM
THE NEIGHBORING SYRIA.
400 TROOPS WILL JOIN NATO
FORCES AND STAND READY TO
ACT IF SYRIA INTENDS TO
UNLEASH CHEMICAL WEAPONS.
FOX'S LELAND VITTERT IS IN
OUR MIDDLE EAST BUREAU.
LELAND, JUST A FEW DAYS AGO
THE HEAD OF NATO SAID THE
ASSAD REGIME IS ABOUT TO
COLLAPSE.
WHY DEPLOY THESE TROOPS NOW?
>> Reporter: IT REALLY HAS
TO DO WITH SHOWING
SOLIDARITY WITH THE TURKS
WHO ARE CLEARLY VERY SCARED
AND TIMING COMES A COUPLE
DAYS AFTER WE LEARNED THAT
THE SYRIANS WERE MIXING
CHEMICAL WEAPONS TO POSSIBLY
USE.
SO THIS IS THE UNITED STATES
AND NATO'S WAY OF REALLY GET
BEING BEHIND TURKEY, A CLOSE
ALLY SAYING WE SUPPORT YOU.
THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE WAS
QUICK TO POINT OUT THAT THE
PATRIOT MISSILES ARE JUST
THAT, DEFENSIVE WEAPONS THAT
WILL BE PUT DOWN ALONG THE
SYRIAN BORDER TO PROTECT
SYRIA, PROTECT TURKEY FROM
ATTACKS BY SYRIAN JETS OR
SCUD MISSILES THAT WOULD FLY
IN BUT THAT IS NOT EXACTLY
THE WHOLE STORY.
THE PATRIOTS COULD BE EASILY
PROGRAMMED AND PUT IN A
NO-FLY ZONE OVER NORTHERN
SYRIA.
SO FAR TURKEY IS DENYING
THAT AS IS NATO SAYING THIS
IS PURELY DEFENSIVE MOVE BY
TURKEY BUT IF THERE WERE TO
BE A NO-FLY ZONE IN THE
COMING MONTHS IT WOULD BE A
GAME-CHANGER BECAUSE THE
REBELS CONTROL MUCH OF
NORTHERN SYRIA.
THE PRESIDENT ASSAD IS USING
HIS AIR FORCE AND THE FIRST
REAL STEP TO PROVIDE SIS --
ASSISTANCE TO REBELS TO
OVERCOME PRESIDENT ASSAD'S
REGIME WOULD BE A NO-FLY
ZONE.
WE HAVE TO READ BEHIND THE
HEADLINES TO SEE WHAT ELSE
THE PATRIOT MISSILES COULD
MEAN FOR THE LARGER
CONFLICT.
ALISYN: THAT IS GOOD
CONTEXT.
WHAT IS RUSSIA SAYING NOW
ABOUT THE ASSAD REGIME?
>> Reporter: YESTERDAY THEY
CAME OUT AND SAID, ALL RIGHT,
WE THINK THERE IS A
POSSIBILITY PRESIDENT ASSAD
WOULD FALL.
THIS IS ONE OF THOSE THINGS
SPEAKING TO TRUTH AS THIS
RUSSIAN DIPLOMAT DID MAY NOT
EXACTLY JIVE WITH THE PARTY
LINE.
INSIDE BASEBALL HERE AS
RUSSIA CAME OUT TODAY AND
FORCEFULLY GOTTEN BEHIND
PRESIDENT ASSAD SAID, NO, NO,
OUR DIPLOMAT WAS MISQUOTED.
HE WAS SAYING WHAT THE
OPPOSITION WAS SAYING.
A LITTLE FANCIFUL.
THERE WAS HOPE AS THE
HUMANITARIAN CRISIS
INCREASES INSIDE SYRIA THERE
ARE MANY MORE HUNDREDS IF
NOT THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE
DYING INSIDE SYRIA THAT
RUSSIA MAY BE LOOSENING TIES
TO PRESIDENT ASSAD.
SADLY FOR THE UNITED STATES
AND ALLIES WE FOUND OUT THAT
RUSSIA IS CONTINUING TO HOLD
FAST WITH PRESIDENT ASSAD
THEIR LONG TIME ALLY AND
HAPPY TO SEE HIM KILL AS
MANY OF HIS OWN CITIZENS AS
HE WOULD LIKE.
ALISYN: THANKS LELAND.
BILL: YOU THINK ABOUT THE
LAST TWO YEARS OF HEADLINES
AND THINK ABOUT THIS REGION
HOW MUCH IT DOMINATED THE
COVERAGE WE'VE HAD AND HERE
AND ALL OVER THE WORLD
FRANKLY.
HERE IS SYRIA IN THE MIDDLE
OF ALL THIS MESS HERE BUT
HEADLINES OUT OF TURKEY,
LIBYA, AND INTO IRAN WAY TO
THE EAST BUT SPECIFICALLY
WITH REGARD TO THESE PATRIOT
BATTERIES, PATRIOT MISS SIS
ILLS -- MISSILES, ADVANCE TO
HERE IS THE BORDER THAT
SEPARATES TURKEY AND SYRIA.
ABOUT 500 MILES FROM WEST TO
EAST.
YOU HEARD LELAND TALK ABOUT
THE PATRIOT TREAT MISSILE
BATTERSRIES.
THERE IS 500 MILE BORDER.
YOU HAVE A COUPLE OF
SIGNIFICANT BORDER CROSSINGS
HERE AND OVER HERE.
DAMASCUS THE CAPITAL CITY IS
DOWN IN THIS AREA.
IT IS OUR UNDERSTANDING THAT
THE TWO BATTERIES THE U.S.
WILL SEND, 400 TROOPS WILL
GO ALONG WITH THAT, YOU'RE
TALKING ABOUT AN AREA MAYBE
60 MILES NORTH OF THE BORDER,
SAID TO BE DEFENSIVE
MEASURES ONLY.
SO THIS GOES ALONG WITH WHAT
WE'VE HEARD FROM GERMANY AND
ALSO THE NETHERLANDS
AGREEING TO SEND SOME
PATRIOT MISSILE BATTERIES
THERE AS WELL ALONG WITH
TROOPS AS WELL.
YOU'RE LOOKING ABOUT 1200
TROOPS BETWEEN THE THREE
COUNTRIES.
YOU WANT TO CONTAIN IT.
SO FAR YOU'VE BEEN PRETTY
GOOD KEEPING IT WITHIN THE
BORDERS OF SYRIA.
IF IT SPILLS OVER YOU'RE
LOOKING AT AREA ALREADY
RACKED BY WAR FOR TWO YEARS.
WHAT CAN HAPPEN THEN?
THEY WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT
DOESN'T.
WE'LL WATCH THAT.
ALISYN: NEXT THREE WEEKS
OBVIOUSLY WILL BE CRITICAL.
WE'RE JUST GETTING STARTED
HERE.
WE HAVE A HEARTBREAKING
STORY OF HEROISM LINKED TO
THE HORRIBLE OREGON MALL
SHOOTING.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT A MAN WHO
PUT HIS OWN LIFE TO TRY TO
SAVE ANOTHER.
BILL: A FORMER U.S. MARINE
LOCKED UP IN MEXICO ON WHAT
HIS FAMILY CALL AS TRUMPED
UP CHARGE.
THE DESPERATE PLEA FOR THE
GOVERNMENT'S HELP AND
SERIOUS CONCERNS NOW THAT
HIS LIFE IS IN DANGER.
>> I ASKED YOU TO CONTINUE
TO PRAY FOR HIM.
WE GOT A CALL FROM HIM LAST
NIGHT.
HE'S JUST IN A REALLY TOUGH
SITUATION BECAUSE IT'S
PUBLIC IN MEXICO AT THIS
POINT.
SO WE ARE PRAYING THAT YOU
WILL PRAY FOR HIS PROTECTION
AND HIS QUICK RELEASE.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS KAREN ANJEREMIAH.
THEY DON'T KNOW IT YET,
BUT THEY' GONNA FALL IN LOVE,
GET MARRIED,
HAVE A COUPLE OF KIDS,
[ children laughing ]
MOVE TO THE COUNTRY,
AND LIVE A LONG, HAPPY LIFE
TOGETHER
WHERE THEY ALMOST NEVER FIGHT
ABOUT MONEY.
[ dog barks ]
BECAUSE RIGHT AFTER
THEY GET MARRIED,
THEY'LL FIND
SOME RETIREMENT PEOPLE
WHO ARE PAID ON SALARY,
NOT COMMISSION.
THEY'LL GET
STRAIGHTFORWARD GUIDANCE
AND BE ABLE TO FOCUS ON OTHER
THINGS, LIKE EACH OTHER,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT STARTED LONG AGO.
THE JOY OF GIVING SOMETHING
EVERYTHING YOU'VE GOT.
IT TAKES PASSION.
AND IT'S NOT LETTING UP
ANYTIME SOON.
AT UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company,
WE UNDERSTAND THAT COMMITMENT.
AND ALWAYS HAVE.
SO DOES AARP,
AN ORGANIZATION
SERVING THE NEEDS
OF AMERICANS 50 AND OVER
FOR GENERATIONS.
SO IT'S NO SURPRISE
MILLIONS HAVE CHOSEN
AN AARP Medicare Supplement
Insurance Plan,
INSURED BY UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company.
LIKE ALL STANDARDIZED
MEDICARE SUPPLEMENT PLANS,
THEY HELP COVER
SOME OF THE EXPENSES
MEDICARE DOESN'T PAY.
AND SAVE YOU UP TO THOUSANDS
IN OUT-OF-POCKET COSTS.
TO FIND OUT MORE,
REQUEST YOUR
FREE DECISION GUIDE.
CALL OR GO ONLINE TODAY.
AFTER ALL,
WHEN YOU'RE GOING THE DISTANCE,
IT'S NICE TO HAVE
THE EXPERIENCE AND COMMITMENT
TO GO ALONG WITH YOU.
KEEP DREAMING. KEEP DOING.
GO LONG.
ALISYN: A LARGE EARTHQUAKE
SHAKING SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA
THIS MORNING.
THE QUAKE WITH A MAGNITUDE
OF 6.4, IT STRUCK IN THE
PACIFIC OCEAN OFF THE
SOUTHERN COAST OF AVALON,
CALIFORNIA, AND ABOUT 170
MILES FROM MEXICO.
NO REPORTS OF DAMAGE OR
INJURIES AND NO TSUNAMI
WARNING HAS BEEN ISSUED BUT
COMING UP WE'LL TALK WITH A
SEISMOLOGIST TO SEE IF THIS
COULD BE THE START OF
SOMETHING BIGGER.
BILL: THERE ARE NEW CONCERNS
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON WILL NOT TESTIFY
ABOUT THE ATTACKS IN
BENGHAZI.
BOTH THE HOUSE AND SENATE
FOREIGN RELATIONS COMMITTEES
HAD ANNOUNCED SHE WOULD
TESTIFY AND IN FACT THAT
WOULD HAPPEN IN ABOUT A
WEEK'S TIME.
NOW THE STATE DEPARTMENT
SAYS THAT IS NOT SUCH A DONE
DEAL.
CONGRESSMAN ED ROYCE IS ON
THE HOUSE FOREIGN AFFAIRS
COMMITTEE.
HE CHAIRS THE TERRORISM
HE IS MY GUEST NOW AND, SIR,
GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
>> GOOD MORNING.
BILL: WHAT DO YOU READ INTO
THIS?
>> BILL, SINCE THE BEGINNING
WE HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE TO GET
ANSWERS BUT NOW WE HAVE THE
ACCOUNTABILITY REVIEW
BOARD'S REPORT WHICH IS
DEWEY HAS TO BE SHARED WITH
CONGRESS.
WE EXPECT THE SECRETARY OF
STATE TO COME AND ANSWER
SOME QUESTIONS THAT FRANKLY
HAVE BEEN ASKED BY THE MEDIA
AND BY THE HOUSE AND THE
SENATE.
ONE OF THOSE QUESTIONS IS
HOW IS IT POSSIBLE WE HAD NO
CONTINGENCY PLAN?
HOW IS IT POSSIBLE THAT OVER
SIX-HOUR PERIOD OF ATTACKS
WE DIDN'T HAVE ANY
HELICOPTER GUNSHIPS, WE
DIDN'T HAVE ANY MANNED
DRONES THAT COULD BE USED TO
DEFEND THAT COMPOUND?
WE DIDN'T HAVE ANY QUICK
REACTION TEAM IN THE THEATER
THAT COULD BE SENT IN TO
DEFEND OUR PERSONNEL?
WE LOST AN AMBASSADOR HERE
AFTER ALL, AS WELL AS OTHER
PERSONNEL.
AND THEN THERE IS THE WHOLE
QUESTION OF THE EXPLANATION
BECAUSE WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT
THE FACT THAT OUR AMBASSADOR
ON THE GROUND HAD EXPRESSED
CONCERNS ABOUT AL QAEDA AND
THE AL QAEDA CAMPS
INCREASING THEIR OPERATIONS
AND THE ATTACKS, FRANKLY
THAT IT CLOSED DOWN THE
BRITISH, THE RED CROSS, EVEN
THE U.N., WE'RE STEPPING UP,
WE'RE STEPPING UP THE
DEFENSE OF THEIR FACILITIES,
AND INSTEAD, YOU KNOW, THIS
FALLS ON DEAF EARS.
AND SO THERE ARE REAL
ANSWERS TO BE, TO BE GIVEN
HERE.
SOMEBODY KNOWS THESE
ANSWERS.
IT IS THE SECRETARY OF
STATE'S RESPONSIBILITY AND
IT WAS ON 9/11.
SOMEBODY FORGOT TO CIRCLE
THE CALENDAR.
BILL: INDEED ON THAT, ON ALL
THOSE POINTS BUT SECRETARY
CLINTON SUGGESTED SHE IS
MORE THAN WILLING TO
TESTIFY.
THE QUESTION IS WHAT WOULD
BE HOLDING HER BACK?
NOW THERE'S A REVIEW BOARD
THAT'S LOOKING AT THIS AT
THE STATE DEPARTMENT.
WOULD YOU GIVE THEM THE
BENEFIT OF THE DOUBT?
PERHAPS IT'S NOT DONE JUST
YET?
PERHAPS IT IS NOT FINISHED?
DOES IT TAKE 3 1/2 MONTHS?
>> THIS IS WHAT IS JUST SO
FRUSTRATING.
NOT THAT IS JUST TOOK SO
LONG.
IF YOU'VE SEEN THE NEWS
REPORTS, A RECENT REPORT A
FEW WEEKS AGO, ABOUT A MONTH
AFTER, A MONTH AFTER,
REPORTERS WERE ON THE SITE
FINDING TWO OF THE 9/11
MEMOS SENT BY OUR AMBASSADOR
TO THE FOREIGN MINISTER OF
LIBYA AND TO THE BENGHAZI
POLICE CHIEF EXPLAINING
THEIR CONCERNS.
THAT VERY DAY THERE HAD BEEN
A POLICE OFFICER, BENGHAZI
POLICE OFFICER, SUSPICIOUSLY
TAKING PHOTOGRAPHS.
THEY WERE ASKING FOR ASSETS
TO HELP DEFEND THAT EMBASSY.
SO YOU THINK ABOUT THE FACT
THAT THE FBI HAD NOT SECURED
THAT SITE.
HERE IT IS POSSIBLE FOR
REPORTERS TO FIND THIS
INFORMATION AND SHARE IT
WITH US BUT WE'RE NOT
GETTING STRAIGHT ANSWERS AND
HAVEN'T GOTTEN STRAIGHT
ANSWERS YET.
I WOULD SAY THREE MONTHS
LATER IT IS TIME FOR SOME
ANSWERS.
BILL: IF SECRETARY CLINTON
DOES NOT TESTIFY, IS THE
TRUTH ON BENGHAZI BURIED?
>> NO BECAUSE WE'RE GOING TO
EXERCISE OVERSIGHT AND WE
ARE GOING TO GET THAT REPORT
AND WE WILL EVENTUALLY HAVE
OUR SECRETARY OF STATE
TESTIFY AS TO WHAT ACTUALLY
HAPPENED.
DURING THAT TESTIMONY WE
WILL FINALLY GET SOME
ANSWERS TO SOME VERY
PERTINENT QUESTIONS BECAUSE
THE NECESSITY OF HAVING THE
CONTINGENCY PLAN, WHEN YOUR
ALLIES PUT IN PLACE A
CONTINGENCY PLAN AND YOUR
OWN AMBASSADOR HAS EXPRESSED
HIS CONCERNS THAT HIS
PERSONNEL MAY BE ATTACKED
FROM AL QAEDA, AND YOU'RE
MONITORING AL QAEDA'S
PRESENCE AND THEN YOU, AND
THEN YOU DISTANCE YOURSELF
FROM THE ARGUMENT THAT IT'S
A AL QAEDA ATTACK ON 9/11,
FRANKLY NONE OF THIS MADE
ANY SENSE FROM THE
BEGINNING.
SO IT IS FINALLY TIME, IF
WE'RE GOING TO LEARN FROM
THIS AND WE NEED TO, THAT'S
WHY THAT LAW IS THERE.
THAT IS WHY THE 1986 ACT WAS
PASSED, FOREIGN
ACCOUNTABILITY REVIEW BOARD
FOR THAT REPORT FROM THE
STATE DEPARTMENT TO THE
CONGRESS.
WE EXPECT THAT REPORT.
BILL: THERE IS ANOTHER PAGE
ON THIS THAT'S YET TO TURN
AND WE'LL SEE WHETHER THAT
HAPPENS.
ED ROYCE, THANK YOU, SIR.
>> THANK YOU.
BILL: 19 MINUTES PAST.
ALISYN: BILL, THERE IS A
BIZARRE SITUATION INVOLVING
AN AMERICAN HERO.
[APPLAUSE]
MEDAL OF HONOR RESIPIENT
DAKOTA MEYER IS RECOVERING
AFTER BEING ATTACKED.
WE'LL INVESTIGATE WHAT
HAPPENED.
BILL: MYSTERY THERE.
THERE IS DEADLINE ON THE
HEALTH CARE EXCHANGE.
STATES MUST DECIDE TODAY TO
SET UP THEIR OWN EXCHANGES
OR LET THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT TO DO IT FOR
THEM.
WE'LL ASK DR. MARC SIEGEL
WHAT IT MEANS FOR YOUR
HEALTH CARE IN AMERICA SOON.
♪
EAT GOOD FATS.
AVOID BAD.
DON'T GO OVER 2000...
1200 CALORIES A DAY.
CARBS ARE BAD. CARBS ARE GOOD.
THE STORY KEEPS CHANGING.
SO I'M NOT LISTENING...
TO ANYONE BUT MYSELF.
I KNOW BETTER NUTRITION
WHEN I SEE IT:
GREAT GRAINS.
GREAT GRAINS CEREAL STARTS
WHOLE AND STAYS WHOLE.
SEE THE SEAM?
MORE PROCESSED FLAKES LOOK
NOTHING LIKE NATURALRAINS.
YOU CAN'T ARGUE WITH
NUTRITION YOU CAN SEE.
GREAT GRAINS.
SEARCH GREAT GRAINS
AND SEE FOR YOURSELF.
FOR MULTI GRAIN FLAKES TT ARE
ANXCELLENT SOURCE OF FIBER
TRY GREAT GRAINS
BANANA NUT CRUNCH
AND CRANBERRY ALMOND CRUNCH.
I TELL THEM DENTURES ARE
VERY DIFFERENT TO REAL TEETH.
THEY'RE ABOUT 10 TIMES SOFTER
AND MAY HAVE SURFACE PORES
WHERE BACTERIA CAN GROW
AND MULTIPLY.
POLIDENT
IS SPECIFICALLY DESIGNED
TO CLEAN DENTURES DAILY.
ITS UNIQUE MICRO-CLEAN FORMULA
KILLS 99.9%
OF ODOR CAUSING BACTERIA
AND HELPS DISSOLVE STAINS,
CLEANING IN A BETTER WAY
THAN BRUSHING WITH TOOTHPASTE.
THAT'S WHY I RECOMMEND
USING POLIDENT.
[ Male Announcer ] POLIDENT.
CLEANER, FRESHER,
BRIGHTER EVERY DAY.
ALISYN: UPDATE FROM THE
TERRIBLE TRAGEDY IN OREGON,
THE OREGON MALL WHERE THAT
GUNMAN SHOT AND KILLED TWO
PEOPLE BEFORE TAKING HIS OWN
LIFE IS REOPENING TODAY.
WE UNDERSTAND SECURITY WILL
BE RAMPED UP AND CRISIS
COUNSELORS ON HAND.
THIS COPS AS WE HEAR FROM
THE ACCUSED SHOOTER'S FAMILY
OF THE HIS AUNT SERVED AS
HIS LEGAL GUARDIAN SINCE HIS
MOM DIED WHEN HE WAS THREE.
SHE IS TEARFULLY APOLOGIZING
SAYING THIS IS NOT THE BOY
SHE KNEW.
>> FOR JACOB'S MOM, I'M SO
SORRY FOR JACOB CAUSED SO
MUCH PAIN AND TRAUMA.
HE WAS ALWAYS A GOOD BUY
AND -- BOY AND CARING.
HE L xJPLAYING WITH LITTLE
KIDS.
THIS IS COMPLETELY OUT OF
CHARACTER.
ALISYN: WELL THE GUNMAN WAS
APPARENTLY ESTRANGED FROM
THAT AUNT WHO RAISED HIM.
THERE IS NO WORD ON ANY
POSSIBLE MOTIVE.
BILL: WE'RE HEARING STORIES
OF HEROISM THROUGH ALL THIS
INCLUDING ONE MAN WHO TRIED
TO HELP VICTIM CINDY YUILLE.
FIRST HE THOUGHT THE SHOTS
WERE SOMETHING COLLAPSING IN
THE MALL.
HE TOLD HIS FAMILY TO HIDE
AND RAN TO HELP HER.
>> I DON'T KNOW WHY I DID.
JUST INSTINCT I GUESS.
I DON'T KNOW.
MY ADRENALINE WAS GOING.
I WAS NEVER WORRIED ABOUT
BEING SHOT OR ANYTHING LIKE
THAT.
I WAS JUST THERE TO HELP
PEOPLE.
BILL: HE SAID TWO OTHER
PEOPLE TRIED TO HELP CINDY
BUT IT WAS TOO LATE FOR HER.
HE STAYED BY HER SIDE UNTIL
POLICE FORCED HIM TO LEAVE
THE MALL SAYING HE DID NOT
FEEL RIGHT LEAVING HER
ALONE.
>> THERE ARE NEW DETAILS
ABOUT A TROUBLING INCIDENT
INVOLVING MEDAL OF HONOR
RESIPIENT DAKOTA MEYER.
HE IS RECOVERING AFTER HE
WAS ALLEGEDLY ATTACKED BY AN
18-YEAR-OLD LAST WEEKEND.
FOX'S ANNA KOOIMAN IS HERE
WITH THE LATEST.
THIS IS PECULIAR.
WHAT MORE DO WE KNOW ABOUT
THIS?
>> Reporter: DAKOTA MEYER
RECENTLY SPOKE WITH OUR RICK
LEVENTHAL.
HE SAID HE WAS HIT OVER THE
HEAD WITH A BOTTLE AND
KICKED AND BEATEN ON THE
GROUND BY A GROUP OF UP TO
10 OR MORE PEOPLE.
HE WOKE UP HOSPITAL WITH
THREE STAPLES IN HIS HEAD.
MEYER SAYS THIS.
HE GAVE US A STATEMENT.
HE SAID THE CIRCUMSTANCES
ARE UNFORTUNATE AND DOESN'T
GO BEYOND THAT THE
ALTERCATION BROKE OUT AT AN
EVENT FACILITY IN COLUMBIA,
KENTUCKY, CALLED, THE RED
BARN.
WE'RE WAITING TO FIND OUT
FROM POLICE SPECIFICS ON
SUNDAY'S AT KERRTATION.
AUTHORITIES SAY THE SEVERITY
OF CHARGE AGAINST ALLEGED
TEENAGE ATTACKER SUGGESTS
THAT DAKOTA MEYER WAS SEE
REMEMBERLY INJURED.
HE WAS HURT BAD ENOUGH TO BE
TREATED AND RELEASED AT A
LOCAL HOSPITAL.
THE 18-YEAR-OLD IS CHARGED
WITH SECOND DEGREE ASSAULT
FOLLOWING THE FIGHT THAT
HAPPENED IN THE EARLY HOURS
ON SUNDAY.
DAKOTA MEYER IS THE
RECIPIENT OF THE MED TALL OF
HONOR WHICH HE RECEIVED LAST
YEAR FOR HIS ROLE IN A 2009
FIGHT AGAINST THE TALIBAN IN
AFGHANISTAN.
MEYER KILLED EIGHT
INSURGENTS AND SAID TO SAVE
THE LIVES OF 13 AMERICAN AND
23 AFGHAN SOLDIERS.
MEYER WAS RECENTLY ON THE
"FOX & FRIENDS" TALKING
ABOUT THE EVENTS THAT EARNED
HIM THE MEDAL OF HONOR.
HE WAS 21 AT THE TIME OF THE
FIGHT WITH THE TALIBAN,
GUYS.
ALISYN: ANNA, THIS IS NOT
THE ONLY CONTROVERSY THAT
SURROUNDED DAKOTA MEYER.
>> Reporter: YOU'RE
ABSOLUTELY RIGHT ABOUT THAT
AS WELL.
MEYER FILED A LAWSUIT
AGAINST A FORMER EMPLOYER.
BEA SYSTEMS, DEFENSE
CONTRACTOR ACCUSED HIM OF
HAVING ALCOHOL PROBLEMS AND
BEING MENTALLY UNSTABLE.
MEYER CLAIMS THE COMPANY
LASHED OUT AGAINST HIM
BECAUSE MEYER VOICED
DISREGARD FOR BAE SELLING
HIGH-TECH SNIPER SCOPES TO
THE PAKISTANI MILITARY.
FOR DETAILS SURROUNDING
SUNDAY'S ALTERCATION WE DO
HAVE A CALL INTO POLICE.
BACK TO YOU.
ALISYN: ANNA KOOIMAN, THANKS
FOR THE UPDATE.
BILL: HE HAS HAD A HECK OF A
LIFE SINCE COMING HOME AND
BEING HONORED AT THE
WHITE HOUSE.
BILL: A U.S. MARINE IS BEING
HELD AT A MEXICAN PRISON FOR
WHAT HIS FAMILY SAYS IS AN
HONEST MISTAKE.
THEY SAY HIS LIFE IS IN
DANGER.
WE'LL TALK TO THE FAMILY
ATTORNEY ABOUT THE EFFORTS
TO GET HIM OUT SAFELY.
HERE IS HIS FATHER.
>> THE SITUATION NOW THAT
WE'VE GONE PUBLIC AND THAT
IS OUR CONCERN AT THIS POINT.
YOU KNOW, IT IS CHAOS DOWN
THERE.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
SOMETHING MADE YOUR JAW DROP?
CAMPBELL'S HAS 24 NEW SOUPS
THAT WILL MAKE IT DROP OVER,
AND OVER AGAIN.
♪
FROM JAMMIN' JERK CHICKEN,
TO CREAMY GOUDA BISQUE.
SEE WHAT'S NEW FROM CAMPBELL'S.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
TO TELL REAL PEOPLE ABOUT
OUR NEW 15 UNDER $15 MENU.
OH MY GOODNESS!
OH MY GOSH,
THIS LOOKS AMAZING!
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR NEW MAINE STAYS!
15ENTREES UNDER $15,
SEAFOOD, CHICKEN AND MORE!
OOTHE TILAPIAWITH ROASTEDEGETAB!
I'M ACTUALLY LOOKING AT
THE WO GRILLED CHICKEN
WITH PORTOBELLO WINE SAUCE.
AT PORK CHOP
WAS GREAT!
NO MORE
FAST FOOD FRIDAY'S!
WE'RE GOING TO GO
TO RED LOBSTER.
YEP.
[ Male Announcer ]
COME TRY OUR NEW MENU
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
SALAD, SANDWICHES, AND MORE.
BILL: 9:31.
WE'RE WATCHING THE STREETS
OF CAIRO, EGYPT NOW.
THIS IS A DAY BEFORE THE
VOTE BEGINS ON THIS NEW
CONSTITUTION, A DRAFT OF
THAT CONSTITUTION, WHERE
EGYPTIANS WILL BE VOTING FOR
SEVERAL DAYS.
THIS, WE UNDERSTAND, IS A
PRO-MORSI CROWD, THE CURRENT
PRESIDENT OF EGYPT.
AND THERE ARE RIVAL PROTESTS
TAKING PLACE THROUGHOUT
CAIRO.
WE'RE WATCHING THIS TO SEE
WHAT HAPPENS.
4:31 IN THE AFTERNOON.
YOU'RE COMING OUT OF FRIDAY
PRAYERS FROM THE MOSQUE
RIGHT BEFORE SUNDOWN.
THE BIG VOTE GOES DOWN
TOMORROW IN EGYPT.
>>> CLOSER TO HOME NOW, A
DESPERATE PLEA FOR HELP FROM
THE FAMILY OF A FORMER U.S.
MARINE LOCKED UP IN A
MEXICAN JAIL.
THE FAMILY OF JOHN HAMMAR
SAYS HE IS STUCK BEHIND BARS
BECAUSE OF AN HONEST
MISTAKE.
THERE IS WORD HE MIGHT BE IN
DANGER.
THE YOUNG WAR VETERAN WAS ON
A ROAD TRIP WHEN HE TRIED TO
CROSS THE MEXICAN BORDER
WITH A SHOTGUN THAT WAS A
FAMILY HEIRLOOM.
HE IS LOCKED UP ON GUN
CHARGES IN MEXICO.
HAMMAR'S FATHER SAYS THEY
ARE NOT LOSING HOPE AND MANY
PEOPLE ARE BEHIND HIM.
>> IT IS CHAOS DOWN THERE,
YOU KNOW.
THERE IS PEOPLE COMING AND
GOING THAT ARE GOOD PEOPLE
AND BAD PEOPLE.
I GET A CALL THE OTHER NIGHT
IN THE WEE HOURS OF THE
MORNING FROM A TEACHER THERE
IN THERE ON THE GROUND, HE
SAID, JOHN, WE READ ABOUT
THIS STORY AND THERE IS GOOD
PEOPLE HERE.
YOU KNOW, WE'RE NOT ALL
CARTEL MEMBERS.
WE'RE NOT ALL BAD PEOPLE.
I SAID I KNOW.
I UNDERSTAND.
SHE SAID, IT DOESN'T HELP
YOU BUT, YOU KNOW, WE'RE
PRAYING THAT YOU GET YOUR
SON HOME.
BILL: THAT IS THE FATHER
SPEAKING THERE.
STEVE HARRIGAN NOW LIVE IN
OUR BUREAU IN MIAMI.
STEVE, WHAT IS THE FAMILY
SAYING ABOUT THEIR SON AND
THE PRISON HE IS IN NOW?
>> Reporter: BILL, IT HAS
REALLY BEEN A FOUR-MONTH
ORDEAL FOR THE FAMILY.
THEY BEGAN GETTING
THREATENING PHONE CALLS
INSIDE THE PRISON DAYS AFTER
JOHN HAMMAR WAS ARRESTED.
THE FIRST CALL WAS A DEMAND
FOR $1800 TO BE SENT VIA
WESTERN UNION OR THE CALLER
SAID YOUR SON WOULD BE
KILLED.
OLIVIA HAMMAR SAID THE CALL
MADE HER PHYSICALLY ILL.
>> WE HAVE YOUR SON AND
WE'RE GOING TO KILL HIM.
YOU KNOW, I HAD THIS REALLY
WEIRD RESPONSE, I SAID, NO,
WE'RE GOING TO CALL THE
CONSULATE.
HE WAS LIKE, THEY CAN'T HELP
YOU.
>> Reporter: IT WAS ONLY
AFTER THOSE NUMEROUS THREATS
THAT JOHN HAMMAR WAS MOVED
FROM THE PRISON'S GENERAL
POPULATION INTO A STORAGE
ROOM, BILL.
BILL: WHO ELSE IS PUSHING
FOR HIS RELEASE?
WHO ELSE IS GIVING HIM
SUPPORT?
>> Reporter: THROUGHOUT THIS
FOUR MONTHS THE FAMILY HAS
BEEN INITIALLY LOW-KEY BUT
THAT DIDN'T GET THEM
ANYWHERE.
NOW THEY'RE BECOMING VERY
PUBLIC.
A LOT OF FRIENDS AND FAMILY
AND ONLINE PETITIONS AS WELL
AS ELECTED OFFICIALS.
THE FAMILY'S CONGRESSWOMAN
HAS IMPLIED THAT THE STATE
DEPARTMENT IS NOT DOING
ENOUGH TO FREE JOHN HAMMAR.
>> I AM VERY FRUSTRATED THAT
WITH THE RESPONSE OF THE
STATE DEPARTMENT.
IT IS VERY
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
IC, IT IS VERY COLD.
AND I DON'T WANT TO SAY THAT
IT'S THE STATE DEPARTMENT'S
FAULT.
OF COURSE THE MEXICAN
GOVERNMENT IS AT FAULT.
THE MEXICAN AUTHORITIES ARE
THE RESPONSIBLE ONES.
>> Reporter: QUESTIONS TOO
ABOUT THE LEGAL PROCESS SO
FAR.
HAMMER HE IS ATTORNEY IN
MEXICO TOLD US ONE OF THE
HEARINGS THAT HAMMER HAD NO
TRANSLATOR PRESENT EITHER.
BACK TO YOU.
BILL: STEVE HARRIGAN FROM
THE STORY ON THE LEGAL
ASPECT NOW.
ALISYN: JOINING US IS JOHN
HAMMAR'S FAMILY ATTORNEY,
EDDIE LEVY.
HE IS WITH US LIVE FROM
MEXICO CITY.
GOOD MORNING, EDDIE.
>> GOOD MORNING, AISYN.
GOOD TO TALK TO YOU.
ALISYN: LET ME MAKE SURE WE
HAVE THE STORY CORRECT.
JOHN HAS BEEN HELD SINCE
AUGUST.
HE WAS TRAVELING THROUGH
MEXICO ON A ROAD TRIP WITH A
BUDDY.
THEY WERE GOING TO
COSTA RICA TO GO SURFING.
WHY DID JOHN HAVE THIS
ANTIQUE GUN WITH HIM?
>> I'LL TELL YOU THE WAY I
UNDERSTAND THEY WERE GOING
TO GO HUNTING IN COSTA RICA
AND NICARAGUA.
THEY HAD A SINGLE SHOTGUN IN
WINNEBAGO KIND OF A CAMPER.
THEY HAD TO GO THROUGH
MEXICO TO GET THERE.
THAT IS WHERE THEY WERE
GOING TO USE IT, WHICH IS
SPORTING GUN USED IN THE
UNITED STATES OF AMERICA.
ALISYN: HE DID ALL THE RIGHT
THINGS.
HE DECLARED THE GUN.
HE FILLED OUT ALL THE
PAPERWORK.
HE ALERTED OFFICIALS THAT HE
HAD THE GUN AND YET THEY
STILL ARRESTED HIM.
NOW WE UNDERSTAND THAT THE
PRISON WHERE HE IS BEING
HELD IS NOTORIOUS FOR
HOUSING VERY DANGEROUS
CRIMINALS, MEMBERS OF THE LO
IS THE ZETAS DRUG CARTEL.
WE HAVE BEEN REPORTS HE IS
CHAINED TO HIS BED IN THE
CELL, THE PRISON OFFICIALS
FEARED HE MIGHT TRY TO
ESCAPE.
THE STATE DEPARTMENT WAS
ASKED ABOUT ALL OF THIS
YESTERDAY.
LET ME PLAY FOR YOU THEIR
RESPONSE.
>> THIS IS UNBELIEVABLE THAT
THE MEXICAN GOVERNMENT IS
NOT STEPPING IN TO HELP US
WHILE THEY TAKE OUR MONEY
AND TAKE ALL THE HELP WE
GIVE THEM.
IT IS INCREDIBLE THAT OUR
OWN U.S. GOVERNMENT IS NOT
DOING ALL THAT WE CAN TO
BRING HAMMAR HOME FOR
CHRISTMAS.
THE FAMILY DESERVES THIS.
HE HAS DONE NOTHING WRONG.
ALISYN: THAT WAS ACTUALLY
ILEANA ROS-LEHTINEN, LEADING
THE CHARGE TO GET HIM OUT.
WHAT THE STATE DEPARTMENT
TOLD US WE FIXED THOSE
PROBLEMS.
HE IS OUT OF THE GENERAL
POPULATION.
HE IS NO LONGER IN DANGER
AND HE IS NOT BEING CHAINED
TO HIS BED.
IS THAT ACCURATE?
>> LET ME TAKE THIS ONE BY
ONE BECAUSE THE, YOUR
PREAMBLE IS CORRECT UP TO A
POINT.
THERE WAS SOMETHING VERY
WRONG THAT TOOK
FIRST PLACE.
WHEN HE WENT TO MEXICO HE
STOPPED IN THE U.S. BORDER
SITE AND ASKED A CUSTOMS AND
BORED PROTECTION AGENT
WHETHER IT WAS LEGAL TO TAKE
THE GUN TO MEXICO, THE
SHOTGUN.
HE RESPONDED, YES.
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO IS FILL
THIS PAPERWORK AND THEN,
YOU'RE ON YOUR WAY.
HE FILLED PAPERWORK BUT THAT
PAPERWORK WAS REALLY TO COME
BACK INTO THE UNITED STATES.
THE UNITED STATES CUSTOMS
PERSONNEL HAD NO BUSINESS
TELLING HIM BECAUSE THEY
DON'T KNOW WHAT MEXICAN LAW
STATES.
MECHANIC CAN LAW STATES THAT
CERTAIN KIND OF WEAPONS,
WHETHER WE LIKE IT OR NOT,
ARE USED OR DEEMED TO BE FOR
EXCLUSIVE USE OF THE ARMED
FORCES.
THAT IS THE ISSUE HERE.
ALISYN: IN OTHER WORDS HE
GOT MISINFORMATION.
HE DIDN'T UNDERSTAND THAT
WHAT THE RULES WERE.
SO THIS SEEMS LIKE A
TECHNICALITY.
BETWEEN TWO COUNTRIES THAT
ARE ALLIES COULD BE QUICKLY
RESOLVED.
WHY IS HE STILL IN PRISON
FROM AUGUST?
>> OKAY.
FIRST OF ALL, IT HAS TO BE
RESOLVED UNDER THE LAW.
I MEAN PEOPLE ARE SAYING
WITH A PHONE CALL.
THINGS CAN HAPPEN BUT WE,
JUST LIKE WE HAVE IN THE
UNITED STATES A COURT
SYSTEM.
BUT LET ME PUT A LITTLE MORE
DEPTH INTO THIS.
YOU'RE CORRECT.
I FILED THREE FEDERAL
INJUNCTIONS.
ONE SHOULD HAVE BEEN GIVEN
TO ME ABOUT FOUR WEEKS AGO.
THE PROSECUTOR DIDN'T EVEN
RESPOND TO IT BECAUSE WE
ALLEGE AND WE PROVED
VIOLATIONS OF JOHN'S MEXICAN
CONSTITUTIONAL RIGHTS.
I'M STILL WAITING RIGHT NOW
FOR THE JUDGE TO ISSUE HIS
JUDGMENT BECAUSE HE COULD BE
FREE WITHIN 24 HOURS ONCE HE
FIND THOSE VIOLATIONS.
I ALREADY TALKED TO THE
JUDGE MORE THAN TWO TIMES.
NOW WE'RE GOING, IF WE NEED
WE'LL TAKE IT UPSTAIRS.
WE'LL TAKE IT TO THE MEXICAN
SUPREME COURT.
ALISYN: OKAY.
>> RIGHT NOW THIS IS AN
ISSUE.
IT IS A TECHNICALITY BUT IT
GETS BETTER HERE.
YOU SEE THE CALIBER OF THE
GUN WHICH IS .410, WHAT IS
SEEMED KNOWN FOR EXCLUSIVE
USE FOR THE ARMY.
THE BULLETS ARE NONEXCLUSIVE
ONLY THE SHOTGUN.
ONLY THING MAKING IT OKAY
LIKE ADMINISTRATIVE FINE IT
IS .18 MILLIMETERS.
THAT IS THE SIZE OF YOUR
FINGER, ALISYN.
THAT IS WHAT IS RIDICULOUS.
ALISYN: EDDIE, A LOT OF
STUFF HERE TAKEN ON FACE
VALUE DOES SOUND RIDICULOUS.
I UNDERSTAND YOU SAY IT HAS
TO GO THROUGH A COURT
PROCESS.
OKAY.
IS HE GETTING A TRIAL?
IS HE SCHEDULED FOR TRIAL?
>> OKAY, HE IS BUT I'LL TELL
YOU, RIGHT NOW I'M PUTTING
THE MEXICAN JUDICIAL SYSTEM,
BECAUSE OF TWO JUDGES REALLY
AND A PROSECUTOR WHO DIDN'T
USE HIS PROSECUTORIAL
DISCRETION, THAT HE COULD
HAVE USED IT.
THE FIRST PROSECUTOR MADE A
BIG MISTAKE IN MEASURING THE
SHOTGUN.
THE PROSECUTOR'S OWN EXPERT
HAD ANOTHER MEASUREMENT.
SO I HAVE MY EXPERT BECAUSE
WE BELIEVE ANYWAY THAT
MEASUREMENT IS INCORRECT
THAT WAS TAKEN.
THAT'S WHAT IS MAKING THE
DIFFERENCE BETWEEN LIBERTY
AND PRISON RIGHT NOW.
BUT WE BELIEVE AND WE'RE
VERY, VERY CERTAIN THAT JOHN
IS GOING TO COME HOME, I CAN
TELL YOU THAT.
ALISYN: I AM COMFORTED BY
YOUR OPTIMISM AS WE ALSO
KNOW JOHN SUFFERS FROM PTSD.
HE SERVED MULTIPLE TOURS OF
DUTY IN AFGHANISTAN AND
IRAQ.
IN FACT HE WAS IN A
GUNBATTLE IN FALLUJAH IN
2004.
HOW HE IS DOING TODAY?
>> LET ME TELL YOU BECAUSE I
HAVE SPOKEN TO HIM LATELY,
HIS FAMILY HAS.
WE DECIDED TO DO, HAVE SOME
STRATEGY I'M NOT AT LIBERTY
TO DISCUSS BECAUSE I'M GOING
TO THE COURT HEARINGS.
JOHN, LET ME TELL YOU THIS
FOR THE PUBLIC.
IT IS GREAT WE'RE ALL
PUSHING FOR HIM AND WE NEED
YOUR HELP IN THAT.
LET ME TELL YOU, JOHN IS A
TOUGH COOKIE.
SEMPER FI, MARINES, PREPARE
THEM REALLY GOOD.
YOU STATED SOMETHING ELSE
WHICH IS VERY TRUE, HE WAS
MOVED OVER, WHEN I GOT INTO
THE CASE BECAUSE OTHER
LAWYERS HAD BEEN THERE AND
THERE WAS SOME LEGAL
MANEUVERING IF YOU WILL THAT
TOOK PLACE.
AFTER THIS I SPOKE TO THE
JUDGE PERSONALLY BECAUSE I
WANTED TO CROSS-EXAMINE THE
MEXICAN CUSTOMS AGENT THAT
SHOULD HAVE RELEASED HIM
ANYWAY.
THERE WERE TWO COURT
HEARINGS SET, ONE FOR
NOVEMBER 17th, ONE FOR
NOVEMBER 23rd.
SO THE JUDGE CONTINUED
HEARINGS UNTIL JANUARY 17th,
I SAY, NOVEMBER 30th WE'RE
READY TO GO TO TRIAL.
I'M IN NEW YORK WITH MY KIDS
IN THANKSGIVING I GET A
PHONE CALL, JOHN WAS TAKEN
TO COURT ON NOVEMBER 23rd,
WITHOUT HIS LAWYER PRESENT,
THAT'S ME AND MOST IMPORTANT
THEY TALKED TO HIM.
AND I WAS ADAMANT AND
FURIOUS BECAUSE THEY REALLY
WANTED TO PUSH HIM TO KIND
OF PLEAD GUILTY.
OF COURSE HE DIDN'T.
YEAH, LET ME TELL YOU.
AFTER HIS FIRST LAWYERS
WANTED HIM SAID YOU WOULD BE
OUT IN THREE YEARS.
I WILL NOT ALLOW HIM TO
PLEAD TO A FELONY.
NO WAY.
ALISYN: OF COURSE YOU ARE.
YOU ARE CONVINCED OF HIS
INNOCENCE AS HE IS.
AND HIS FAMILY.
>> I AM AS THE FAMILY.
WE'LL BRING HIM OUT.
ALISYN: WE LIKE YOUR
OPTIMISM.
EDDIE, THANKS VERY MUCH FOR
THE UPDATE ON EXACTLY WHAT
IS GOING ON DOWN THERE.
>> MY PLEASURE, ALISYN.
THANKS FOR HAVING ME.
EVERYBODY KEEP WRITING
LETTERS.
KEEP PRAYING PLEASE.
AND I NEED ALL THE SUPPORT,
ESPECIALLY PRAYING.
WE'LL, I'LL BE FILING LET ME
TELL YOU THAT RIGHT NOW.
-- WITH THE JUDICIARY.
ALISYN: I'M SURE OUR VIEWERS
WILL COMPLY WITH YOUR
REQUESTS.
THIS IS TOPIC THAT IS NEAR
AND DEAR TO THEIR HEARTS
NOW.
THANKS SO MUCH, EDDIE.
BILL: YOU INNINGS INED THIS
PRISON TOO.
ALISYN: VERY DANGEROUS.
NOTORIOUS.
BILL: MEMBERS OF THE ZETAS
AND OTHER DRUG CARTELS ARE
HELD THERE.
SAID TO BE A TOUGH, TOUGH
PLACE.
THEY ARE FORMER SPECIAL
FORCES MEMBERS OF THE
MEXICAN ARMY.
SAID TO BE HIGHLY INVOLVED
IN HUMAN SMUGGLING AND KNOWN
TO KILL MIGRANTS FOR NOT
RUNNING DRUGS FOR THEM.
AT 1:00 HOUR WITH MEGYN THE
PARENTS OF THE MARINE WILL
BE ONTO TELL THEIR SIDE OF
THE STORY.
ALISYN: HEART-BREAKING FOR
THEM.
BILL: MEANTIME, IT IS
DECISION DAY FOR THE STATES
ON THE PRESIDENT'S HEALTH
CARE LAW, DID YOU KNOW THIS,
TODAY?
WILL THEY OR WILL THEY NOT
PARTICIPATE IN THE NEW
HEALTH INSURANCE MARKETS AND
WHAT WILL THAT DECISION MEAN
FOR PATIENTS EVERYWHERE?
MARC SIEGEL ON THAT.
ALISYN: ROCK AND ROLL RIGHT
INTO A HOME.
NOW HOW A GIANT BOULDER
ENDED UP INSIDE ONE FAMILY'S
GARAGE.
re
so awesomely delicious
my husband and I
can't stop eating 'em!
What's...that...
on your head?
Can curlers!
Tomato basil.
Potato with bacon.
We've got
a lotta empty cans.
[ Male Announcer ] Hear from
our chefs on Facebook
this Friday!
Social Security are just numbers
thinkin a budget.d... cans.
Well, we worked hard for those
benefits.
We earned them.
And if Washington tries to cram
decisions about the future...
of these programs into a last
minute budget deal...
we'll all pay the price.
AARP is fighting to protect
seniors with responsible...
solutions that strengthen
Medicare and...
Social Security for generations
to come.
We can do better than a last
minute deal...
that would hurt all of us.
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
And also to build my career.
So I'm not about to always let
my frequent bladder urges,
or the worry my pipes
might leak get in the way
of my busy lifestyle.
That's why I take care,
with VESIcare.
Once-daily VESIcare can help
control your bladder muscle
and is proven to treat
overactive bladder
with sympts of
frequent urges and leaks
day and night.
If you have certain stomach or
glaucoma problems,
or trouble emptying
your bladder,
do not take VESIcare.
VESIcare may cause allergic
reactions that may be serious.
If you experience swelling of
the face, lips,
throat or tongue,
stop taking VESIcare
and get emergency help.
Tell your doctor right away if
you have severe abdominal pain,
or become constipated for three
or more days.
VESIcare may
cause blurred vision,
so use caution while driving
or doing unsafe tasks.
Common side effects
are dry mouth, constipation,
and indigestion.
I've worked hard
to get to where I am...
and I've got better
aces to go
than always
going to the bathroom.
So take charge of your symptoms
by talking to your doctor
and go to vesicare.com
for a free trial offer.
BILL: THIS IS SIGNIFICANT
DAY FOR OBAMACARE.
TODAY IS THE DEADLINE FOR
STATES TO DECIDE WHETHER
THEY RUN A KEY PIECE OF THIS
LAW OR LEAVE IT TO THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT.
IT IS CALLED AN EXCHANGE AND
WHAT DOES IT MEAN FOR YOU?
DR. MARC SIEGEL, A MEMBER OF
OUR FOX NEWS MEDICAL A-TEAM,
PROFESSOR OF MEDICINE AT NYU
LANGONE MEDICAL CENTER IN
NEW YORK AND GOOD MORNING TO
YOU, DOCTOR.
THE EXCHANGE IS WHAT?
DEFINE AND REMIND US WHAT IT
IS.
>> THE EXCHANGE IS VIRTUAL
THING.
IT TAKES PLACE ON A COMPUTER
LIKE MEDICARE PART-D.
YOU PLUG IN YOUR ZIP CODE,
BILL, IT TAKES YOU TO A
PLACE WHERE YOU GET CHOICES.
WHAT HEALTH POLICY DO YOU
WANT?
WHAT SUBSIDY DO YOU QUALIFY
FOR?
MAYBE YOU QUALIFY FOR
MEDICAID.
ALL OF THAT IN THE SAME
PLACE ONLINE.
BILL: GOT IT.
EACH STATE IS SUPPOSED TO
SET ONE OF THESE EXCHANGES
UP IF YOU DO NOT HAVE WHAT,
INSURANCE THROUGH YOUR
EMPLOYER OR YOUR OWN PRIVATE
INSURES YOU CAN GO TO THIS
EXCHANGE?
>> AS WE TALKED ABOUT HE
HAVE, THE EMPLOYER MAY SAY
WE CAN'T COVER YOU ANYMORE
AND MORE AND MORE MILLIONS
COMING TO THE MARKET THAT
WILL HAVE TO GET IT FROM
THESE EXCHANGES.
BILL: 19 STATES ALREADY SAID
WE'RE NOT GOING TO RUN OUR
OWN EXCHANGE IN OUR STATE.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN FOR
EVERYDAY AMERICANS LIVING IN
THAT STATE?
>> BY THE WAY, BILL, I THINK
THE REASON THEY'RE SAYING IT
ONE MIGHT ARGUE THERE'S
POLITICS BUT ALSO ISSUES OF
FISCAL RESTRAINT.
THOSE 19 STATES MAY BE
SAYING HEY, WE CAN'T AFFORD
TO DO THIS.
WE PLAY NOT BE ABLE TO
AFFORD TO SET UP THESE
EXCHANGES.
THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT MAY,
BY CURRENT ESTIMATES WILL
HAVE TO SPEND ALMOST A
BILLION DOLLARS IN THOSE
STATES SETTING UP EXCHANGES.
NOW FOR PEOPLE OUT THERE
WHAT THIS WILL MEAN, IF YOU
LIVE IN ONE OF THOSE 19
STATES, COME NEXT OCTOBER,
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO
PROBABLY DEAL WITH AN
EXCHANGE THAT THE FEDS SET
UP FOR THE STATES AND THE
PROBLEM WITH THAT, IN MY
OPINION, IS THAT IT ADDS
ANOTHER LEFT OF BUREAUCRACY,
BECAUSE, BILL, SINCE WE
DON'T HAVE PORTABILITY OF
INSURANCE, SINCE INSURANCE
COMPANIES ARE STATE BY STATE,
IT'S YOUR STATE GOVERNMENT
THAT IS USED TO DEALING WITH
YOUR LOCAL INSURANCE
COMPANIES, NOT THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT.
SO IF THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT
IS RUNNING THE EXCHANGE THEY
MAY NOT BE USED TO DEALING
WITH YOUR LOCAL BLUE
CROSS-BLUE SHIELD.
BILL: THAT'S A GREAT POINT.
THERE ARE 17 STATES AND
WASHINGTON, D.C. SAY THEY
WILL SET UP AN EXCHANGE WITH
THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT.
AM I BETTER OFF TO LIVE IN
ONE OF THOSE STATES OR NOT?
>> THE FAR WEST, NEW YORK,
STATES LIKE THAT, I THINK
YOU ARE.
I THINK YOU'RE BETTER OFF.
BILL: YOU ARE WHAT?
>> I THINK YOU'RE BETTER OFF
LIVING IN A STATE WHERE THE
STATE IS RUNNING THE
EXCHANGE RATHER THAN THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT.
THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT HAS
NOT GIVEN OUT THE PLANS HOW
THEY WILL DO THE EXCHANGE
BUT THE STATES ARE ALREADY
RAMPING UP FOR IT, ONES
DOING IT.
IF YOU GO TO MINNESOTA'S
WEBSITE YOU SEE A TUTORIAL.
THAT IS TERRIFIC.
YOU HAVE UNTIL NEXT OCTOBER
BUT PEOPLE BETTER START
LEARNING NOW.
I THINK YOU'RE BETTER OFF
LIVING IN A STATE WITH AN
EXCHANGE.
BILL: YOU DEAL WITH MEDICINE
EVERY DAY.
THIS IS YOUR PROFESSION.
THAT'S WHY WE HAVE YOU
SITTING HERE.
YOU SAY THE STATES BETTER
UNDERSTAND THEIR OWN
DISTRIBUTION OF HEALTHCARE
BETTER THAN WASHINGTON DOES?
>> BY FAR BECAUSE THE
INSURANCE COMPANIES ARE
STATE BY STATE.
THEY CAN'T GO ACROSS STATE
LINES.
WHEN AN INSURANCE COMPANY
HAS A PROBLEM IN A STATE
THEY GO TO THE STATE
GOVERNMENT, NOT THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT.
THE STATES ARE USED TO
DEALING WITH INSURANCE
COMPANIES.
I HOPE PEOPLE ARE OUT THERE
LIVING IN A STATE WITH AN
EXCHANGE.
BILL: YOU CAN PUT STATES IN
ONE CATEGORY OR THE OTHER.
THAT SEEMS TO BE WAY THEY
ARE BREAKING DOWN.
WE'RE WAITING FOR TWO STATES
TO MAKE A DECISION.
VIRGINIA AND FLORIDA.
BOTH WITH REPUBLICAN
GOVERNORS.
WE'LL SEE WHAT THEY SAY.
>> BILL, THERE WILL BE A LOT
OF CONFUSION AND A LOT OF
MONEY SPENT.
I'LL TELL YOU THAT.
BILL: DR. MARC SIEGEL.
THANK YOU, SIR.
GOOD TO SEE YOU AS WELL.
ALISYN, WHAT IS NEXT?
ALISYN: A WOMAN LUCKY TO BE
ALIVE.
SHE WAS TRAPPED UPSIDE DOWN
IN HER CAR OVERNIGHT FOR
EIGHT HOURS.
WE HAVE HER STORY.
BILL: U.S. SENDING MISSILES
AND TROOPS TO HELP SECURE
TURKEY'S BORDER WITH SYRIA.
WHAT DOES THAT SAY ABOUT
AMERICA'S INVOLVEMENT AND
THE BLOODY CIVIL WAR INSIDE
OF SYRIA?
A CLOSER LOOK AT THAT AND
WHAT IT MEANS.
BILL: A WOMAN IN
MASSACHUSETTS RECOVERING
AFTER SHE SPENT A FREEZING
NIGHT TRAPPED UPSIDE DOWN IN
HER MINIVAN.
SHE IS 27 YEARS OLD.
MEGYN HAYLEY IS HER NAME.
CRASHED HER VAN WEDNESDAY
NIGHT IN WOODS ON CAPE COD.
A MAN WALKING HIS DOG CAME
ACROSS THE WRECK NEXT
MORNING.
FIREFIGHTERS CUT DOWN THE
TREES AROUND HER.
REMOVED PIECE OF THE CAR IN
ORDER TO GET HAYLEY OUT
AFTER SHE SPENT THE NIGHT
INSIDE.
>> TOOK 30 MINUTES TO SAFELY
GET HER OUT.
SHE HAD A SERIOUS HEAD
WOUND.
SHE WAS ABLE TO SPEAK.
BILL: SHE IS IN THE HOSPITAL
LISTED AS STABLE.
SHE IS LUCKY TO BE ALIVE.
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
♪ .
ALISYN: WELL IT'S A VERY
FESTIVE SONG AND IT'S A
FESTIVE TIME BUT OF COURSE
THERE IS DOWNSIDE TO ALL
THAT FESTIVITY.
TIME OF YEAR WHEN MANY
AMERICANS HIT THE HOLIDAY
PARTIES AND SOME WILL HAVE
WAY TOO MUCH TO DRINK.
ONE OF THOSE IS OUR OWN
WILLIAM LA JEUNESSE WHO JUST
TOOK PART IN A POLICE
APPROVED STUDY HE WANTS US
TO KNOW ON BOOZE.
HE IS LIVE IN LOS ANGELES.
WILLIAM, HOW MUCH WINE DID
YOU CONSUME?
>> TOO MUCH.
I HAD SEVEN GLASSES.
SOME OF MY FRIENDS HAD UP TO
14.
BUT TELL YOU THE HOLIDAYS DO
MEAN ALCOHOL.
THAT MEANS A RISK OF DRIVING
DRUNK.
WHICH IS ONE REASON PEOPLE
ARE BUYING POCKET
BREATHOLYZERS.
HOW DO YOU KNOW YOU'RE OVER .08?
ARE THESE ACCURATE.
WE FOUND WHAT YOU THINK YOU
KNOW ABOUT ALCOHOL IS
PROBABLY WRONG.
SAID I WOULD TAKE YOU HOME
TONIGHT WOULD YOU BE WILLING
TO DO SO?
YOU SAID YOU WOULD BUT WHAT
OUR AUDIENCE DIDN'T KNOW, ED
HAD BEEN AND
COAX FOR PAST THREE HOURS.
EIGHT IN TOTAL.
>> I HAD FIVE GLASSES OF
WINE.
I'M STARTING TO SLUR MY
SPEECH.
>> Reporter: ASHLEY, WHAT
DID YOU DRINK?
>> SIX GLASSES.
>> Reporter: I HAD SEVEN
GLASSES OF WHITE WINE.
>> 10 COARSE LIGHTS.
>> EIGHT JACK AND COKES.
>> 13 VODKA.
>> Reporter: OUR NIGHT OF
BOOZING HAD ONE PURPOSE.
TO DISPEL MISCONCEPTIONS
ABOUT DRINKING AND DRIVING.
A BIGGER PERSON, FATTER
OVERWEIGHT, CAN THEY HANDLE
ALCOHOL BETTER?
>> NO.
PEOPLE ARE HEAVIER HAVE LESS
WATER BECAUSE FAT HAS LESS
WATER.
>> Reporter: IS IT POSSIBLE
TO FEEL SOBER AT THE BAR AND
NOT BE SOBER BEHIND THE
WHEEL?
>> NO.
ALCOHOL VOLUME,
BLOOD-ALCOHOL CONTENT
CONTINUES TO RISE AFTER YOUR
LAST DRINK FOR A GOOD 30
MINUTES OR SO.
>> Reporter: AS WE SAW WITH
THE VOLUNTEER ASHLEY.
>> I'M DRUNK AND I HONESTLY
WOULD BELIEVE I BLOW OVER
THE LEGAL LIMIT.
>> MAKE A TIGHT SEAL.
.069.
>> COME ON?
I'M HAMMERED.
THE.
>> YOUR BLOOD-ALCOHOL
CONTINUES TO RISE FOR 30
MINUTES.
>> Reporter: COFFEE,
EXERCISE, SHOWER, DOES THAT
SOBER YOU UP?
>> NO.
WAKES YOU UP.
GIVES YOU MORE STIMULATED
EFFECT.
YOU'RE STILL FEELING
EFFECTS.
YOU'RE STILL DRUNK.
>> LEARN THAT NO MATTER WHAT
YOU DRINK YOU CAN ONLY
METABOLIZE SO MUCH.
REGARDLESS WHAT YOU FEEL
YOUR ALCOHOL LEVEL IS STILL
HIGHER THAN YOU THINK.
>> Reporter: SO MY
BLOOD-ALCOHOL AFTER THOSE
SEVEN GLASSES OF WINE WAS .14.
THAT IS ALMOST TWICE THE
LEGAL LIMIT.
OTHER THREE GUYS WERE .15.
THE WOMAN WAS.09.
YOUR LIVER CAN METABOLIZE
ONE DRINK AN HOUR.
ANYTHING OVER THAT,
ESPECIALLY ON EMPTY STOMACH
IS LIKE POURING ALCOHOL INTO
YOUR BRAIN.
FOOD DOES NOT STOP YOU FROM
BECOMING DRUNK OR MAKE YOU
LESS DRUNK.
AS FOR THE BREATHALYZERS,
TWO OF THEM WERE REPEATEDLY
WRONG.
ONE WAS PRETTY GOOD.
THE COPS SAY THESE DEGRADE
OVER TIME.
DON'T LEAVE IT IN THE GLOVE
BOX AND RISK YOUR LICENSE ON
IT A YEAR LATER.
ALISYN: YOU ARE AN INTREPID
REPORTER.
THANKS VERY MUCH, WILLIAM
LA JEUNESSE.
BILL: KUDOS FOR SHOWING UP
TODAY.
ALISYN: WHAT AN ASSIGNMENT.
BILL: MY OH MY.
A BREAK HERE.
A JEEP GRAND CHER,
TELL THEM
IT'S LIKE BEING NESTLED
IN AN EIGHT-WAY, ADJUSTABLE,
HEATED AND VENTILATED SEAT
SURROUNDED BY A 500-WATT
SOUND SYSTEM
WHILE FLOATING ON A SUSPENSION
MADE OF BILLOWY CLOUDS.
OR YOU COULD JUST HAND THEM
YOUR KEYS.
♪
TRY RUNNING FOUR.NING
A RESTAURANT IS HARD,
FORTUNATELY WE'VE GOT INK.
IT GIVES US 5X THE REWARDS
ON OUR INTERNET, PHONE
CHARGES AND CABLE,
PLUS AT OFFICE SUPPLY STORES.
REWARDS WE PUT RIGHT
BACK INTO OUR BUSINESS.
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
WE'VE EVER WANTED TO DO
AND INK HELPS US DO IT.
MAKE YOUR MARK
WITH INK FROM CHASE.
YOU WON'T TAKE OUR FUTURE.
AIDS AFFECTS US ALL.
EVEN BABIES.
CHEVRON IS WORKING TO STOP
MOTHER-TO-CHILD TRANSMISSION.
OUR EMPLOYEES AND THEIR FAMILIES
ARE PART OF THE FIGHT.
AND WE'RE WINNING.
AT CHEVRON NIGERIA, WE HAVEN'T
HAD A REPORTED CASE IN 12EARS.
AIDS IS STRONG.
BUT WE ARE STRONGER.
AND AIDS...
♪
AIDS IS GOING TO LOSE.
GREGG: BRAND-NEW HOUR, FOX NEWS
ALERT ON THE NEW FALLOUT IN THE
INVESTIGATION INTO THE TERROR
ATTACKS IN LIBYA.
THE CHAIRMAN OF THE HOUSE
INTELLIGENCE COMMITTEE,
REPUBLICAN MIKE ROGERS SAYING
THAT HE BELIEVES THE STATE
DEPARTMENT SHOWED GROSS
NEGLIGENCE BY NOT PROVIDING
ADEQUATE SECURITY IN BENGHAZI IN
THE WEEKS LEADING UP TO THE
ATTACK THAT KILLED OUR U.S.
AMBASSADOR AND THREE OTHERS.
SO MUCH MORE IN THIS STORY.
I'M BILL HEMMER, WELCOME.
WE ARE NOT IN THE CONDITION THAT
WILLIAM LA JEUNESSE IS IN
TODAY.
ALISYN: WE FEEL BETTER BECAUSE
WE TONIGHT HAVE SEVEN GLASSES OF
WINE.
I'M ALISYN CAMEROTA IN FOR
MARTHA MACCALLUM TODAY.
THERE ARE ALSO CONFLICTING
REPORTS THIS MORNING ABOUT WHEN
SECRETARY MUCH STATE HILLARY
CLINTON WILL TESTIFY BEFORE
CONGRESS OR EVEN IF SHE WILL
ABOUT THIS TERROR ATTACK.
CATHERINE HERRIDGE IS LIVE IN
WASHINGTON.
CATHERINE, GIVE US ALL THE
LATEST.
>> Reporter: FIRST OF ALL I'LL
START WITH THE COMMENTS BY THE
RUB CHAIRMAN OF THE INTELLIGENCE
COMMITTEE WHERE HE DESCRIBES THE
STATE DEPARTMENT'S ACTIONS PRIOR
TO THAT ATTACK AS GROSS
NEGLIGENCE, THAT MEANS THERE IS
SUFFICIENT EVIDENCE THAT THE
STATE DEPARTMENT BEARS SOME
RESPONSIBILITY FOR THE DEATHS OF
FOUR AMERICANS.
AS WE FIRST REPORTED HERE AT FOX
NEWS, BASED ON THE CLASSIFIED
CABLE THERE WAS AN EMERGENCY
MEETING IN BENGHAZI AFTER
SECRETARY CLINTON'S OFFICE WAS
SPECIFICALLY WARNED THE BENGHAZI
CONFLICT COULD NOT WITHSTAND A
COORDINATED ASSAULT.
THERE WERE TEN CAMPS WITHIN
BENGE LINKED TO ISLAMIST
MILITIA'S AS WELL AS AL-QAIDA.
>> IT'S BEEN TYPICAL THE NAMES
ARE HELD FOR 48 HOURS.
WE DON'T KNOW HOW MANY THEY ARE,
WHAT STATES THEY ARE FROM, WHO
THE FAMILIES ARE AND WE WOULD
LIKE TO TALK TO THEM.
>> Reporter: NEW FOX POLLS SHOW
BY A WIDE MARGIN THAT AMERICANS
THINK PRESIDENT OBAMA SHOULD
HAVE SENT U.S. TROOPS TO
BENGHAZI TO STOP THE 9/11
ATTACKS.
AMERICANS ARE DIVIDED OVER THE
ADMINISTRATION'S HANDLING WITH
THE ATTACK WITH A SLIM MAJORITY
BELIEVING THAT IT COAST AMOUNT
TO A COVER UP.
ALISYN: WILL CONGRESS TULLAHOMA
LEE GET TO SEE THE COMPLETE
REPORT?
>> Reporter: THAT IS AN
IMPORTANT QUESTION.
A REVIEW OF THE REGULATIONS BY
FOX NEWS AND THE REGULATIONS
THAT GOVERN THE STATE DEPARTMENT
APARTMENT INTERNAL INVESTIGATION
KNOWN AS THE ACCOUNTABILITY
REVIEW BOARD OR ARB DOES NOT
SUGGEST THERE IS A SPECIFIC
REQUIREMENT FOR THE ENTIRE
REPORT TO BE GIVEN TO CONGRESS,
JUST AS SECRETARY CLINTON MUST
PROVIDE HER WRITTEN COMMENT TO
CONGRESS WITHIN 90 DAYS OF THE
REPORT'S COMPLETION.
LISTEN CLOSELY TO THIS EXCHANGE
YESTERDAY.
>> WE'LL GET YOU THE STATUTE IF
YOU'D LIKE.
IS THAT THE SECRETARY'S RESPONSE
TO THE ARB'S CONCLUSIONS HAS TO
GO IN WRITING TO THE CONGRESS
WITHIN 90 DAYS OF HER RECEIVING
THE REPORT.
SHE OBJEC OBVIOUSLY WILL INTEND
TO CONSULT WITH THEM EARLIER
THAN THAT AS SHE'S COMMIT.
>> Reporter: IF YOU LISTEN
CLOSELY TO THAT RESPONSE WHAT
YOU HEAR IS THAT THERE IS NOT A
COMMITMENT TO PROVIDE THE ENTIRE
UNVARNISHED REPORT TO CONGRESS,
THERE IS ONLY A REQUIREMENT FOR
CLINTON TO PROVIDE HER OWN
COMMENTS, AND NOW THERE HAS BEEN
THIS BACK AND FORTH OVER WHETHER
IN FACT SHE WILL RECEIVE
THURSDAY NEXT WEEK.
THE STATE DEPARTMENT
CHARACTERIZED THAT AS A DATE ON
THE CALENDAR RATHER THAN A DATE
CERTAIN.
ALISYN: SO MANY QUESTIONS
REMAIN, CATHERINE HERRIDGE,
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
CONGRESS REALLY WANTS THAT
UNVARNISHED RECORD.
BILL: WE HAVE NEW REACTION TO
THE U.N. AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE
BOWING OUT OF THIS.
THE FALLOUT FROM BENGHAZI
WEIGHED HEAVILY ON HER
DECISION.
HILLARY CLINTON RESPONDING TO
THIS DECISION WRITING QUOTE FROM
THE NATIONAL SECURITY COUNCIL,
TO THE STATE DEPARTMENT TO THE
UNITED NATION SUSAN HAS WORKED
TIRELESS TO ADVANCE OUR NATION'S
VALUES.
I AM CONFIDENT SHE WILL CONTINUE
TO REPRESENT THE UNITED STATES
WITH STRENGTH AND KILL.
ALISYN: THERE WAS A LONG LEAD UP
TO THIS OWE DIGS, IT GOES AL
DECISION, IT GOES BACK TO
SEPTEMBER 16 THIS WHEN
AMBASSADOR RICE WENT ON FIVE
SHOWS AND SAID THE ATTACK WAS
NOT PRE-MED TAEUTD.
THAT CONTINUE SREUBTED
INFORMATION THAT WAS KNOWN SET.
ALMOST TWO MONTHS LATER
AMBASSADOR RICE'S NAME IS
MENTIONED AS A TOP CANDIDATE TO
REPLACE OUTGOING HILLARY
CLINTON, AND ALMOST IMMEDIATELY
NEAR LIE 100 REPUBLICAN HOUSE
MEMBERS WRITE TO PRESIDENT OBAMA
DISCOURAGING HIM FROM NOMINATING
HER.
AT THE END OF NOVEMBER
AMBASSADOR RICE MET WITH
REPUBLICAN LAWMAKERS TO DISCUSS
BENGHAZI AND AFTERWARDS G G.O.P.
SENATORS SAY THEY ARE MORE
CONCERNED ABOUT HER RESPONSE TOW
THE ATTACK.
YESTERDAY, DECEMBER 13th
AMBASSADOR RICE WITHDRAWS HER
NAME FROM CONSIDERATION TO BE
THE NEXT SECRETARY OF STATE.
>> ADD THIS TO THE MIX NOW,
QUESTIONS BEING RAISED AFTER NBC
NEWS CORRESPONDENT ANDREA
MITCHELL TALKED ABOUT THE
WITHDRAWAL OF SUSAN RICE AND THE
PERCEPTION OF THE REPUBLICAN
PARTY.
THIS IS WHAT SHE SAID.
ROLL IT.
>> I THINK THAT THIS HAD BECOME
SORT OF AN IMPOSSIBLE CHALLENGE
FOR HER TO BE CONFIRMED.
SHE REALIZED THAT, THE WHITE
HOUSE REALIZED IT AS WELL.
I THINK THEY KNOW THAT THEY ARE
ON GOOD POLITICAL FALLEN GROUND
AS YOU POINTED OUT.
THIS IS NOT GOING TO HELP
REPUBLICANS AT ALL THE FACT THAT
A WOMAN, AND A WOMAN OF COLOR
HAS BEEN FORCED OUT OF THE
CONFIRMATION PROCESS EVEN BEFORE
SHE WAS NOMINATED.
BILL: A WOMAN AND A WOMAN OF
COLOR.
I HAVE CHRIS WALLACE WITH ME.
HOW ARE YOU DOING.
>> GOOD MORNING, BILL.
BILL: I DON'T KNOW HOW THAT
SQUARES WITH RICE R*
CONDOLEEZZAA RICE OR COLIN
POWELL.
>> AS I HEARD THIS I'M TRYING TO
HELP THE LAST TIME THERE WAS A
WHITE MAN AS SECRETARY OF THE
STATE, BECAUSE MADELEINE
ALBRIGHT BACK TO THE CLINTON
YEARS, I THINK IT WAS WARREN
CHRISTOPHER IN THE FIRST TERM OF
BILL CLINTON BACK IN 96 OVE 96
OR SOMETHING -RPBGTS SO , SO I
DON'T KNOW.
BILL: WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT SUSAN
COLLINS SHE WAS THE MODERATE
FEMALE SENATOR THAT SUSAN RICE
WENT TO CAPITOL HILL TO MEET
WITH.
IF THEY GOT SUSAN COLLINS
SUPPORT SHE'D BE OKAY AND SUSAN
COLLINS CAME OUT AND BLASTED
SUSAN RICE.
>> SUSAN COLLINS IS INTERTING
BECAUSE SUSAN RICE HAD A
CONNECTION TO MAIN.
WHAT HAPPENS WHEN SOMEONE IS
NOMINATED FOR A POSITION THERE
IS A SENATOR FROM THEIR HOME
STATE WHO INTRODUCES THEM TO THE
COMMITTEE, AND IT WAS SUSAN
COLLINS WHO INTRODUCED SUSAN
RICE TO THE COMMITTEE BACK IN
2009, AND YOU'RE QUITE RIGHT.
THERE WERE SOME PEOPLE LIKE
LINDSEY GRAHAM AND JOHN MCCAIN
WHO WERE AGAINST SUSAN RICE AND
I'M NOT SURE ANYTHING WAS GOING
TO SATISFY THEM.
WHEN SHE WENT TO SEE A QUITE
MODERATE REPUBLICAN LIKE SUSAN
COLLINS AND SHE CAME OUT AND
SAID SHE HAD MORE QUESTIONS THAN
BEFORE THE MEETING.
I'VE NEVER SEEN WHEN THERE'S
BEEN A NOMINATION -- EVEN BEFORE
THERE IS A NOMINATION SOMEBODY
IS GOING UP AND DOING THAT
NOMINATION CHARM TOUR TO TRY TO
GREASE THE SKIDS ON THIS KIND OF
A THING TO MAKE IT EASIER TO GET
THE NOMINATION.
THIS SHE DID BEFORE SHE WAS EVEN
NAMED AND IT BACKFIRED
TERRIBLY.
SHE DID BADLY IN EVERY SESSION
THAT SHE HAD WITH REPUBLICANS
AND DEMOCRATS.
BILL: LET'S MOVE ON NOW TO THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
JOHN BOEHNER MAY GO HOME TO OHIO
THIS WEEKEND.
DOES THAT TELL US ANYTHING?
>> NO, I MEAN FIRST OF ALL, I
MEAN THERE ARE TELEPHONES, AND
THERE IS INTERNET.
AT THIS POINT A LOT OF THE STUFF
IS BEING DONE BY STAFF AND THEY
ARE NOT GOING TO THEIR HOMES,
BOTH WHITE HOUSE STAFF AND JOHN
BOEHNER'S STAFF.
THE FACT THAT THEY HAD THE 50
MINUTE NEATING AND IT WAS
DESCRIBED AS FRANK WHICH IN
DIPLOMATIC LANGUAGE BASICALLY
MEANS WE JUST TALKED ABOUT OUR
DISAGREEMENT, NO, WE ARE
NOWHERE.
THERE SEEMS TO BE NO PROGRESS
BEING MADE AND WE ARE ONE WEEK
CLOSER TO THE CLIFF AS OF SUNDAY
IT WILL BE, WHAT, 16 DAYS I
THINK, SO WE'RE GETTING PRETTY
CLOSE.
BILL: NOWHERE YOU'RE SAYING.
YOU TALK TO THESE GUYS EVERY DAY
DOWN THERE IN WASHINGTON.
YOU'RE SAYING WE ARE NOWHERE
CLOSE TO AN AGREEMENT?
>> OH, NO.
I MEAN ABSOLUTELY NOT.
JOHN BOEHNER IS CONTINUING TO
HOLD THE POSITION THAT HE'S NOT
GOING TO BULGE ON TAX RATES.
I THINK HE PROBABLY WOULD, BUT
WHAT HE NEEDS TO DO THAT NOT
JUST A SORT OF POLITICAL COVER
BUT ALSO TO GET IT PASSED BY THE
HOUSE, REPUBLICANS IN THE HOUSE,
IS HE NEEDS SERIOUS SPENDING
CUTS AND EVEN ENTITLEMENT REFORM
AND THERE SEEMS NO DISPOSITION
ON THE PART OF THE PRESIDENT OR
DEMOCRATS TO GO ALONG WITH
THAT.
YOU KNOW, YOU SEE PEOPLE LIKE
DICK DURBIN, LIKE NANCY PELOSI
SAYING FLAT OUT, WE ARE NOT
GOING TO GO FOR ANY CUTS TO
MEDICARE RIGHT NOW, OR
MEDICAID.
SO I THINK THAT WE ARE STILL AT
LOGGERHEADS AND THE RACE FOR
SPENDING CUTS IS GOING NOWHERE.
BILL: PEOPLE STOP ME AND ASK ME
ONE SIMPLE QUESTION.
ARE WE GOING OVER THE CLIFF OR
ARE WE NOT.
TODAY YOU'RE SAYING WE COULD
VERY WELL.
>> I WOULD NOT ANSWER YES TO
THOSE FOLKS THAT ARE ASKING YOU,
IT SURE LOOKS MORE LIKELY THAN A
WEEK AGO.
TWO WEEKS IT MAY NOT SEEM LIKE
MUCH, AN AWFUL LOT CAN GET DONE
IN TWO WEEKS.
NO VACATIONS FOR THE PEOPLE HERE
BUT THEY CAN GET IT DONE IF
THERE IS A WILL.
BILL: WE WILL EYE SEE YOU
SUNDAY.
OUR REGARDS TO WINSTON.
THAT WAS VERY TOUCHING.
THANK YOU, CHRIS.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
BILL: DIRK DURBIN AND KELLY
AYOTTE, TWO OF THE GUESTS
SITTING DOWN WITH CHRIS WALL
AS.
ALISYN: FOX NEWS ALERT, GROWING
TENSIONS IN EGYPT THIS HOUR AS
RIVAL FACTIONS TAKE TO THE
STREETS.
SUPPORT EARTHS AND OPPONENTS
MUCH EGYPTIAN PRESIDENT MOHAMMED
MORSI STAGING MASSIVE RALLIES
ONE DAY BEFORE VOTING ON A DRAFT
CONSTITUTION THAT HAS PLUNGED
THE COUNT ARE COUNTRY INTO A
POLITICAL HOTBED.
HERE IS THE SCENE.
>> Reporter: WE ARE ON THE EAVE
OF THAT CRUCIAL VOTE.
THIS IS WHAT IT'S ALL B. THIS IS
A COPY OF THE DRAFT
CONSTITUTION.
IT IS 63-PAGES LONG, 256
ARTICLES AND IT IS CAUSING A LOT
OF PROBLEMS, INCLUDING IN THE
EGYPTIAN CITY TODAY OF
ALEXANDRIA.
PROTESTORS FOR AND AGAINST
PRESIDENT MOHAMMED MORSI AND THE
CONSTITUTION CLASHING IN THE
STREETS AFTER A CLERIC URGED A
YES VOTE AT FRIDAY PRAYERS, HE'S
NOT SUPPOSED TO DO THAT.
ROCKS WERE TORN, CARS WERE
TORCHED, THERE WERE INJURIES AND
ARRESTS.
SO FAR IN CAIRO IT HAS BEEN
QUIET.
THE MUSLIM BROTHERHOOD, PROMORSI
FORCES GATHERING IN ONE LOCATION
IN FAIRLY BIG NUMBERS.
ALSO BEHIND US HERE IN TAHRIR
SQUARE AND IN THE PRESIDENTIAL
PALACE THE CRITICS OF THE
CONSTITUTION AND PRESIDENT
MOHAMMED MORSI ALSO GATHERING.
SO FAR THE TWO SIDES HAVE STAYED
APART.
ALISYN: IS THERE ANYWAY TO
PROCEED TICKET WHAT WILL HAPPE
PREDICT WHAT WILL HAPPEN THIS
WEEKEND?
>> THERE ARE NO POLLS RIGHT
NOW.
WE HAVE KIND OF AN IDEA OF WHAT
IS GOING TO HAPPEN.
TOMORROW IT IS THE FIRST STAGE
OF POLLING.
ONE-HALF OF THE COUNTRY WILL BE
GOING TO THE POLLS ON THIS
CONSTITUTION.
THE OTHER HALF WILL BE VOTING A
WEEK FROM SATURDAY.
THE POLLS WILL OPEN AT 8:00AM.
WE ARE TOLD THAT TENS OF
THOUSANDS OF TROOPS WILL BE
MOBILIZED.
WE ARE TOLD THAT THE POLLING
MATERIAL IS GOING TO THE POLLING
STATION AND THE JUDGES WILL
MONITOR BUT IT IS SO
DISORGANIZED THAT FORMER
PRESIDENT CARTER CENTER WHICH
HAS OBSERVED HALF THE ELECTIONS
HERE DECIDED THEY ARE GOING TO
SIT THIS ONE OUT, IT IS TOO
DISORGANIZED.
WE WILL BE WATCHING THIS ALL
FOR.
ALISYN: THANK YOU FOR THE UPDATE
FROM CAIRO.
GREGG: BUSY DAY HERE ON A FRIDAY
EDITION OF "AMERICA'S
NEWSROOM."
NEW QUESTIONS NOW AFTER U.S.
TROOPS ARE DISPATCHED NEAR THE
BORDER OF TURKEY AND SYRIA.
IS AMERICA NOW GETTING EVEN
CLOSER TO DIRECT INVOLVEMENT IN
THAT CIVIL WAR?
ALISYN: NEW INFORMATION ON THE
MASSIVE GAS PIPELINE BLAST, WHAT
INVESTIGATORS SAY ABOUT THE
CONDITION OF THE PIPELINE JUST
BEFORE IT EXPLODED.
BILL: THERE IS GROWING
ANGERAFTER A 12-YEAR-OLD GIRL IN
A PWHAOEL CHAIR I WHEELCHAIR IS
DETAINED BY THE TSA AND DEEMED A
SECURITY THREAT.
THIS IS CELLPHONE VIDEO.
YOU'LL SEE MORE OF THIS AND THE
INCIDENT IN THE GIRL'S OWN
WORDS, HER EXPERIENCE.
>> THERE WAS THESE PEOPLE
SAYING, REALLY YOU'RE GOING TO
DO THIS TO HER, YOU'LL HAVE TO
TAKE HER SOMEWHERE PRIVATE TO
WHERE SHE IS NOT OUT IN THE
PRIVATE WHERE EVERYONE CAN SEE
HER.
IT'S MY FAVORITE TIME
OF YEAR AGAIN
AND NOW -- I GOT
A GREAT NEW WAY TO GET DEALS.
IT'S CALLED BANKAMERIDEALS,
FROM BANK OF AMERICA.
I CHOOSE THE CASH BACK DEALS
IN MY MOBILE OR ONLINE BANKING.
I JUST USE MY BANK OF AMERICA
DEBIT OR CREDIT CARD WHEN I PAY.
AND I GET AS MUCH
AS 15% CASH BACK --
PUT INTO MY ACCOUNT.
THIS IS CASH BACK ON TOP OF
OTHER REWARDS I ALREADY GET.
BEST OF ALL -- IT'S FREE.
HAPPY HOLIDAYS.
[ Male Announcer ]
INTRODUCING BANKAMERIDEALS,
FREE FOR
ONLINE BANKING CUSTOMERS.
BILL: NEW INFORMATION ON THIS
MASSIVE GAS PIPELINE EXPLOSION
IN WEST VIRGINIA.
SEE THAT POLICE CAR RIGHT THERE?
TKWAR -FDWARFED BY THAT FLAME
IN THE BACKGROUND.
A PORTION OF THE METAL GAS LINE
HAD THINNED LESS THAN A 10th
OF AN INCH BEFORE THAT BLAST.
THAT WOULD EXPLAIN IT.
>> THE INVESTIGATORS CONDUCTED A
DETAILED ON SITE INVESTIGATION
OF THE RUPTURED PIPE.
THIS EXAMINATION REVEALED THAT
THERE IS ROUGHLY A SIX TO THE
AREA THAT RAN ALONG THE BOTTOM
OF THE PIPE, ALONG THE BOTTOM OF
THE PIPE, RUNNING FOR ABOUT SIX
FEET, WHERE THE PIPE THICKNESS
WAS THINNER THAN DESIGNED.
BILL: THIS IS WHAT YOU GET IN
THE END, LOOK AT THOSE FLAMES.
THE EXPLOSION DESTROYED FOUR
HOMES, CHARRED A HUGE AREA OF
INTERSTATE 77 IN WEST VIRGINIA,
NO SERIOUS INJURIES, THOUGH.
OFFICIALS SAY THE EXACT CAUSE
MAY NOT BE DETERMINED, THOUGH,
FOR SOME TIME.
THEY'VE GOT A CLUE AS YOU CAN
SEE.
ALISYN: THERE ARE MAJOR NEW
DEVELOPMENTS OUT MUCH SYRI SEAR
OUT OF SYRIA.
THE U.S. HELPING TURKEY PROTECT
ITSELF FROM GROWING VIOLENCE IN
THE ENGINE.
LEON PANETTA SIGNED A ORDER TO
SEND TWO U.S. MISSILES TO TURKEY
ALONG WITH 400 AMERICAN TROOPS,
PART OF AN EFFORT TO SECURE THE
SOUTHERN BORDER WITH SYRIA.
CHUCK NASH IS A FORMER RETIRED
NAVY CAPTAIN AND A FOX NEWS
ANALYST.
WE HAVE SENT 400 TROOPS TO THE
BORDER WITH SYRIA.
CAN THIS BE INTERPRETED AS U.S.
TROOPS GETTING INVOLVED IN THE
SYRIAN CONFLICT?
>> I THINK THIS IS MORE
ACCURATELY DESCRIBED AS U.S.
TROOPS HELPING OUT THE NATO
ALLY, THIS IS PURELY A DEFENSIVE
MOVE.
THESE TROOPS ARE NOT BEING PUT
DIRECTLY IN HARM'S WAY, THEY ARE
NOT CROSSING THE BORDER.
THE PATRIOT MISSILE SYSTEM IS A
DEFENSIVE WEAPONS SYSTEM AND
IT'S BEING USED TO HELP THE
TURKS UNDERSTAND THAT NATO IS
WITH THEM ON THIS AND THE U.S.
IS DOING SOMETHING AND TAKING
PART WITH GERMANY AND THE
NETHERLANDS.
ALISYN: YOU SAY THIS IS A
DEFENSIVE MISSION ONLY, BUT
COULD THERE BE A SCENARIO IN
WHICH THESE 400 TROOPS END UP
HAVING TO ENFORCE A NO-FLY-ZONE
OVER SYRIA?
>> THAT IS A POTENTIAL, BECAUSE
YOU DON'T NEED TO NECESSARILY DO
THAT WITH AIRCRAFT.
DEPENDING ON WHERE THE MISSILE
BATTERIES ARE PUT IN PLACE, AND
THE RANGE, THOSE MISSILES ARE
PERFECTLY CAPABLE OF NOT ONLY
SHOOTING DOWN THEATER BALLISTIC
MISSILES WHICH IS THE FIRST
THING THAT EVERYONE WOULD THINK
OF, THE SCUDS TO BE BLUNT,
EVERYTHING IS THINKING ABOUT THE
SCUDS RIGHT NOW BUT YOU COULD
USE THAT SYSTEM TO TARGET MANNED
AIRCRAFT AS WELL OR UAV'S.
ALISYN: WE'VE HEARD FROM LEADERS
INSURANCE NATIONALLY THIS WEEK
WHO BELIEVE THAT THE BASHAR
AL-ASSAD REGIME IS CLOSE TO
COLLAPSING.
AND IF YOU AGREE HOW CLOSE?
>> IT SOUNDS LIKE IT.
EVEN THE RUSSIANS ARE TALKING
ABOUT EVACUATING THEIR PEOPLE.
THEY HAVE A LOT OF ADVISERS IN
THERE, THEY HAVE EMBASSY
PERSONNEL IN THERE AS WELL,
MILITARY ADVISERS, AND SO IF
THEY ARE TALKING ABOUT THAT,
THEN LOOK FOR ACTIVITY AROUND
THE PORTS OF TARTUS AND
LATAKIA.
DEPENDING ON HOW MUCH EQUIPMENT
THEY WOULD RETROGRADE AND GET
THE PEOPLE OUT THOSE TWO PORTS
WOULD BE IMPORTANT AS WELL AS
THE AIRPORTS AROUND DAMASCUS.
ALISYN: MEANING WHAT IF YOU SAW
MORE ACTIVE AROUND THE PORTS
THAT WOULD MEAN BASHAR AL-ASSAD
IS MAKING A RUN FOR IT?
>> HE PROBABLY IS GOING TO WANT
TO GET SOME STUFF OUT OF THERE.
HE WOULD PROBABLY GET FLOWN OUT
BECAUSE THEY WANT TO DO IT WITH
AS FEW OF PEOPLE THAT KNEW ABOUT
IT AS POSSIBLE BECAUSE YOU WOULD
HAVE A MASSIVE COLLAPSE IN THAT
CASE.
NO MATTER HOW THIS TURNS OUT
YOU'LL HAVE A LOT OF BAD PEOPLE
WITH ACCESS TO A LOT OF REALLY
BAD WEAPONS.
AND YOU'VE GOT AL-QAIDA GROUPS
IN THERE.
EVERYBODY IN THE MAIN OPPOSITION
IS CONNECTED WITH THE MUSLIM
BROTHERHOOD, SO THERE REALLY
AREN'T ANY GOOD SCENARIOS FOR
THE END OF THIS THING.
ALISYN: ON THAT CHILLING NOTE
CAPTAIN CHUCK NASH THANK YOU SO
MUCH FOR YOUR INPUT.
>> YOU'RE WELCOME.
BILL: A RUDE AWAKENING FOR SO
MANY THIS MORNING.
WHY THE LOCATION OF AN
EARTHQUAKE ONLY HOURS AGO IS
TELLING.
ALISYN: AND DEVINE INTERVENTION
OR JUST BAD LUCK?
WHAT STOPS TWO THIEVES FROM
ROBBING A CHURCH?
BILL: GUILT.
[LAUGHTER]
FIRST CHRISTMAS.
THESE DEALS ALL SEEM GREAT
AT THE TIME...
BUT LATER...
[ shirt ]
MERRY CHRISTMAS, EVERYBODY!
NOT SO MUCH.
HO HO HO!
THIS ISN'T
THAT KIND OF DEAL.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SAVE ON GROUND SHIPPING
AT FEDEX OFFICE.
Looking back if it wasn't for
Shriners Hospital,.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
things would just be really,
really different.
I lost my leg when I was a kid.
There was a time when
I felt like I wasn't
going to be able to
walk again...
It was a pretty bad accident
But Shriners showed me who
I could be again.
They turned my whole
life around.
Hunter's life is one of nearly
a million changed
by donations from people
like you.
Send your love to the rescue.
Donate today.
ALISYN: BREAKING NEWS TO TELL
YOU RIGHT NOW.
THERE ARE REPORTS OF A SCHOOL
SHOOTING IN NEW TOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
AT THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
OFFICIALS ARE SAYING THERE IS
NOT MUCH INFORMATION BUT WE ARE
GETTING THIS FROM OUR LOCAL FOX
AFFILIATE, FOX 61 THERE.
THEY SAY POLICE ARE REPORTING A
NUMBER OF INJURED PARTIES.
WE ARE NOT SURE IF THEY ARE
ADULTS OR CHILDREN.
THEY SAY THE NATURE OF THE
INJURIES IS NOT CLEAR.
WE ARE GETTING THE INFORMATION
INTO OUR NEWSROOM.
STUDENTS ARE APPARENTLY BEING
ESCORTED FROM THE BUILDING IN
GROUPS.
THERE IS A STAGING AREA THAT HAS
BEEN SET UP FOR PARENTS WHO
NATURALLY WILL BE TERRIFIED TO
RECEIVE THIS NEWS, AND THE
POLICE ARE ON THE SCENE.
SO WE WILL BRING YOU ANY MORE
INFORMATION AS SOON AS WE HAVE
IT ON THIS UNFOLDING STORY.
BILL: BACK TO THAT IN A MOMENT.
IN THE MEAN TIME A POWERFUL
EARTHQUAKE A FEW HOURS AGO
HITTING THE SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA
COAST AND OFF THE WESTERN COAST
OF MEXICO HERE.
6.3 MAGNITUDE, ABOUT 2:30AM
LOCAL TIME, ABOUT 5:30 HERE ON
THE EAST COAST.
ABOUT 160 MILES OFF THE COAST OF
SAN DIEGO HERE AND LOCAL NEWS
REPORTS SAY THAT FOLKS IN LONG
BEACH AND NEWPORT BEACH IN
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA, THEY FELT
THE SHAKING.
DR. JOHN EBOS, A SEISMOLOGIST
FROM BOSTON COLLEGE, TK MORNING
TO YOU, GOOD MORNING TO YOU
DOCTOR.
YOU SAID INTERESTING THINGS TO
OUR PRODUCERS.
YOU SAID THE INTERESTING THING
ABOUT THIS EARTHQUAKE IS THE
LOCATION WHERE IT OCCURRED.
HOW SO IN.
>> THAT'S RIGHT ALL OF THE
EARTHQUAKE WE'VE SEEN OFF OF
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA HAS BEEN ON
THE CONTINENT ITSELF, THIS
EARTHQUAKE OCCURRED IN THE ROCK
WHERE THE CONTINENT HAS DROPPED
AWAY AND NOW WE HAVE PURELY
OCEANIC ROCK, VERY UNUSUAL FOR
EARTHQUAKES IN SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA.
>> I WANT TO SHOW THE FOLKS THE
SAN ANDREAS FAULT, HOW IT
RETURNS ALONG THE ENTIRE WEST
COAST OF CALIFORNIA.
WHAT YOU ARE SAYING, SIR, IS
THAT WHETHER OR NOT THE ONSHORE
ACTIVITY IS RELATED TO THE
OFFSHORE ACTIVITY.
CAN YOU MAKE A CONNECTION OR
NOT?
>> WELL, WE'LL BE STUDYING THAT,
WE DON'T REALLY KNOW.
WHAT WE KNOW IS OBVIOUSLY THE
PACIFIC OCEAN PLATE IS MOVING
RELATIVE TO THE NORTH AMERICAN
PLATE, THE SAN ANDREAS AND THE
OTHER FAULTS ARE THE BOUNDRY.
AWFUL THE DEMORE STATION ARE ON
THE FAULT OR ON EITHER SIDE OF
THE FAULT.
THE QUESTION FOR US IS THERE
SOME PLATE DEFORMATION THAT IS
TAKING PLACE IN THE OCEANIC ROCK
TO THE WEST OF CALIFORNIA, COULD
THAT POSE A THREAT OF
EARTHQUAKES OR EVEN TSUNAMIS.
TSUNAMIS.
BILL: DOES THAT HELP US PREDICT
THE NEXT BIG STPWHOPB.
>> IT COULD HELP US PREDICT THE
NEXT BIG ONE IF WE SEE UNUSUAL
DEFORMATIONS OFFSHORE THAT ARE
ASSOCIATED WITH EARTHQUAKES
ONSHORE.
SO FAR I DON'T KNOW OF ANY
UNUSUAL ONSHORE ACTIVITY.
BILL: THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
DOCTOR JOHN EBUS FROM BOSTON
COLLEGE IN MASSACHUSETTS.
NO TSUNAMI ON THIS ONE, THE
MAGNITUDE WAS NOT BIG ENOUGH TO
CREATE ONE.
THE DEPTH WAS INTERESTING TOO,
ONLY ABOUT SIX MILES, WHICH IS
SHALLOW.
THANK YOU, WE'LL CALL AGAIN ON
YOU DOCTOR.
>> OKAY.
ALISYN: BACK TO BREAKING NEWS
THAT WE JUST REPORTED MOMENTS
AGO, THAT IS OF A SCHOOL
SHOOTING IN NEW TOWN,
CONNECTICUT, ABOUT 50 MILES
OUTSIDE OF NEW YORK CITY.
IT'S A WELL HEALED SUBURB
THERE.
THE STATE POLICE ARE ON SCENE.
THEY SAY THEY ARE RESPONDING TO
A REPORT OF A SCHOOL SHOOTING AT
SANDYHOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEW TOWN.
THEY SAY THERE ARE A NUMBER OF
INJURED PARTIES, THE NATURE OF
THE INJURIES IS NOT CLEAR AT
THIS HOUR.
THEY SAY STUDENTS ARE BEING
ESCORTED FROM THE BUILDING IN
GROUPS.
A STAGING AREA HAS BEEN SET UP
FOR THE AS YOU CAN IMAGINE
TERRIFIED PARENTS WHO ARE
SHOWING UP AT THE SCHOOL.
WE ARE SENDING A REPORTER ON THE
WAY THERE.
WE WILL BRING YOU MORE
INFORMATION AS SOON AS WE HAVE
IT.
BILL: WELCOME BACK.
WE ARE IHE POLICE
DEPARTMENT, ALSO THE SCHOOL IN
SOUTHWESTERN CONNECTICUT.
REPORTS OF A SCHOOL SHOOTING
ONLY MOMENTS AGO.
WE KNOW VERY FEW DETAILS.
BUT THIS IS WHAT WE CAN REPORT.
STATE POLICE HAVE RESPONDED TO
THE REPORT OF A SHOOTING AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
WHICH NOW WE UNDERSTAND IS
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADE, POLICE REPORTING A NUMBER
OF INJURED PARTIES, BUT WE DON'T
KNOW THE EXTENT OF THESE
INJURIES, OBVIOUSLY, AT THIS
POINT.
ALISYN: AND WHO IS INJURED, THIS
MEANS TEACHERS, STUDENTS.
WE ARE TOLD THAT ALL SCHOOLS NOT
JUST THIS SCHOOL ARE ON LOCKDOWN
AFTER THE REPORTED SHOOTING AND
POLICE ARE ON THE SCENE.
WE HAVE SCANT INFORMATION
UNFORTUNATELY.
WE CAN IMAGINE HOW TERRIFIED
PARENTS ARE IF THEY ARE GETTING
INFORMATION FROM THE LOCAL FOX
AFFILIATE.
IT SAYS AFTERNOON KINDERGARTEN
WILL BE CANCELED TODAY.
THERE WILL BE NO MIDDAY BUS
SERVICE.
WE DON'T KNOW IF THAT WAS
PREPLANNED OR IS CONNECTED TO
WHAT IS GOING ON.
SEVERAL TROOPERS ARE RESPONDING
TO THE SCHOOL.
THERE IS A STAGING AREA
OUTSIDE.
KIDS HAVE BEEN LED OUT IN GROUPS
FROM THE SCHOOL.
IT'S A TERRIFYING SITUATION,
OBVIOUSLY FOR ALL PARENTS, NOT
EVEN JUST IN NEWTOWN AND WE WILL
SEE YOU POSTED AND NEW
INFORMATION AS SOON AS WE GET IT
INTO OUR NEWSROOM.
BILL: A LITTLE BIT HERE FROM THE
"ASSOCIATED PRESS."
ACCORDING TO THE SUPERINTENDENT
SPEAKING WITH REPORTERS THERE AT
THE OFFICE IN NEWTOWN THE
DISTRICT HATS BEEN ON LOCKDOWN
AS A PREVENTATIVE MEASURE.
THIS IS IMPORTANT NOW, THE
SUPERINTENDENT'S SECRETARY SAYS
THAT REPORTS OF A SHOOTING ARE
NOT CO CONFIRMED.
WE'LL WORK THROUGH THIS TOGETHER
AND GATHER INFORMATION AS WE
CAN.
IT JUST CROSSED THE WIRES ABOUT
SEVEN MINUTES AGO.
BE PATIENT WITH US AS WE WORK
THROUGH IT.
YOU MENTIONED A NUMBER OF PEOPLE
ESCORTED OUT OF THE BUILDING,
PERHAPS THAT IS THE CASE.
THIS BIT OF INFORMATION FROM THE
SUPERINTENDENT'S OFFICE --
ALISYN: IS COMFORTING, THAT'S
COMFORTING IF IT'S NOT
CONFIRMED, WHERE WE'RE GETTING
OUR INFORMATION IT'S JUST A VERY
TINY BLURB FROM A WEBSITE THERE
THAT SAYS THAT POLICE ARE
REPORTING A NUMBER OF INJURED
PARTIES.
LET'S HOPE THAT IN THE CONFUSION
OF THESE EARLY REPORTS THAT THAT
IS NOT ACCURATE, BUT, AGAIN,
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO KNOW UNTIL
POLICE ARE ABLE TO MAKE A
STATEMENT AND WE ARE ON THE
PHONE WITH THEM AT THIS HOUR.
BILL: WE ARE WORKING THIS
STORY.
AS WE GET MORE INFORMATION
YOU'LL HEAR IT HERE FIRST FROM
THE POLICE AND ALSO THAT
SCHOOL.
IN THE MEANTIME LET'S MOVE
FORWARD ON SOMETHING THAT WE
CAME ACROSS ON OUR LATEST FOX
POLLING NUMBERS NOW.
THE LATEST NUMBERS FROM OUR
POLLING A MONTH AFTER THE
ELECTION, HALF OF AMERICANS
BELIEVE THE GOVERNMENT PROVIDES
TOO MANY SERVICES FOR TOO MANY
PEOPLE.
25% SAY IT'S JUST RIGHT.
20% SAY THE GOVERNMENT PROVIDES
TOO LITTLE.
WHAT ABOUT THIS NOW, A GREAT
PANEL, JUAN WILLIAMS, FOX NEWS
POLITICAL ANAL HR*EUTS, MARY
KATHERINE HAM EDITOR AT LARGE
"HOT AIR.COM, A FOX NEWS
CONTRIBUTOR.
HOW ARE YOU TWO TKOFPLGT MERRY
CHRISTMAS, WHATEVER APPLIES.
I WAS THINKING ABOUT THE POLLING
NUMBER HERE HALF THE PEOPLE
RESPONDING SAYS THE GOVERNMENT
DOES TOO MUCH.
THINK ABOUT THE DEADLINE TODAY
FOR THESE HEALTH EXCHANGES.
PUT THOSE TWO TOGETHER IF YOU
CAN.
>> LOOK IT SEEMS OBVIOUS TO A
LOT OF PEOPLE THAT THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT ESPECIALLY IS VERY
BLOATED.
YOU TALK IN THESE NUMBERS OF
TRILLIONS ARE REALLY HARD TO PUT
IN PERSPECTIVE BECAUSE IT'S MORE
THAN ANY PERSON WILL EVER SEE IN
THEIR LIFETIME USUALLY.
SO I THINK THAT IS PART OF WHERE
THIS IS COMING FROM.
WHEN YOU GET DOWN TO THE NUTS
AND BOLTS OF CUTTING CERTAIN
THINGS, PEOPLE SAY HEY I DON'T
WANT THAT CUT, OR THAT CUT,
THAT'S WHY WE HAVE PROBLEMS WITH
THAT.
AS FAR AS THE HEALTHCARE
EXCHANGES GO I DON'T THINK
ANYBODY SHOULD UNDER ESTIMATE
WHERE YOU LIKE THE BILL OR DON'T
LIKE THE BILL HOW MUCH REALLY
INTRICATE TOUGH WORK IS AHEAD
FOR STATES AND THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT THAT THEY ARE QUITE
BEHIND ON AT THIS POINT IN ORDER
TO ACCOMPLISH THAT.
AND, FRANKLY WHEN THE GOVERNMENT
IS DOING A LOT OF STUFF, IN MY
OPINION, OFTEN THAT IT SHOULD
NOT BE INVOLVED IN, YOU END UP
NOT BEING VERY GOOD AT A LOT OF
THINGS.
BILL: IF THAT'S THE CASE THEN
THAT 49% NUMBER GIGS TO GO
HIGHER.
>> I WOULD NOT BE SURPRISED IF
SOME OF THESE THINGS GO VERY
WRONG AND THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT
IS NOT ABLE TO PIN IT ON CERTAIN
G.O.P. GOVERNORS AND PEOPLE LOOK
AT THE THING AND SAY, HEY WHY
DID YOU DECIDE TO DO THIS GIANT
BILL IF YOU COULDN'T ACCOMPLISH
IT.
BILL: WHAT DO YOU THINK ABOUT
THAT JUAN.
>> I SAW IN THE PAPER, SOMEONE
WAS QUOTED AS SAYING, A
REPUBLICAN, THAT BASICALLY A LOT
OF THE REPUBLICAN GOVERNORS ARE
CUTTING OFF THEIR NOSE TO SPITE
THEIR FACE.
PEOPLE THINK THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT HAS TOO MUCH POWER.
HERE YOU HAVE REPUBLICAN
GOVERNORS REFUSING TO COOPERATE
WITH THE HEALTHCARE PLAN BECAUSE
IT'S PRESIDENT OBAMA'S PLAN AND
GIVING MORE POWER TO THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT TO ESTABLISH THESE
EXCHANGES AND DETERMINE
STANDARDS OF HEALTHCARE INSIDE
THEIR STATES.
BILL: THEY ARE GOING TO SAVE
MONEY BY WAY OF THIS.
>> THEY ARE NOT GOING TO SAVE
ANY MONEY.
BILL: I THINK IT'S TRUE ABOUT
POLICY WHENEVER IT HAPPENS FROM
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT, THERE IS
ALWAYS A YING TO THE YANK, I
YANG.
IF YOU GO TOO FAR VOTERS ARE
GOING TO PULL YOU BACK.
>> WHEN YOU SAY TO VOTERS, YEAH
THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT DOES TOO
MUCH, MAYBE WE SHOULD STOP
HAVING SOCIAL SECURITY OR CUT
BECOME ON MEDICARE, OR WHAT
ABOUT FOOD STAMPS OR
UNEMPLOYMENT.
THEY SAY, NO, NO DON'T DO THAT,
PLEASE, NO WE DON'T WANT TO DO
THAT.
SOMEBODY HAS TO MAKE TOUGH
DECISIONS.
>> ON THE EXCHANGES I DO WANT TO
MAKE THE POINT LIKE 25 STATES
HAVE DECIDED NOT TO -- ABOUT
HALF OF THE STATES HAVE DECIDE.
BILL: 19 OFFICIALLY I THINK.
>> THERE ARE SOME UNDECIDED AS
OF TODAY.
BILL: IT COULD GO TO 25, YOU'RE
RIGHT, CONTINUE.
>> IT'S NOT JUST ABOUT POLITICS,
IT'S ABOUT ACTUAL TECHNICAL
ABILITY TO SET THIS THING UP.
THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT HAS NO
SIGN OF WHAT ITS FEDERAL
EXCHANGE WILL LOOK LIKE.
THE FEDERAL DATA HUB YOU'RE
SUPPOSED TO PLUG INTO HAS NOT
YET BEEN CREATED, THAT'S WHY
THEY ARE WORRIED ABOUT WHAT
THEY'LL BE ABLE TO DO.
AS A MATTER OF LOGISTICS THIS IS
VERY COSTLY, TOUGH, AND THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT BY THE WAY
FOR POLITICAL REASONS DID NOT
GIVE PEOPLE EVEN THE
REQUIREMENTS FOR AN EXCHANGE
HEALTHCARE PLAN UNTIL A WEEK AND
A HALF AGO.
AND SO NOW THESE GUYS ARE HAVING
TO SET THIS UP IN NINE MONTHS.
BILL: GOOD LUCK WITH THAT,
JUAN.
I'LL GIVE YOU THE LAST WORD
HERE.
>> THIS TO ME IS AN ARGUMENT FOR
STATES SAYING, HERE IS WHAT WE
WANT TO DO, HERE IS HOW WE WANT
TO DO IT AND USING THEIR VOICE,
THEIR POWER.
BILL: THEY ARE.
>> WHICH IS THE ARGUMENT IN THE
CONGRESS FROM THE REPUBLICANS
OPPOSING THE BILL SAYING WE WANT
STATES TO HAVE MORE AUTHORITY
AND SET THEIR OWN STANDARDS AND
THAT WAS INSISTED UPON BY
REPUBLICANS, IT WAS A POINT THAT
WAS CONCEDED BY DEMOCRATS AND
NOW YOU HAVE THE REPUBLICAN
GOVERNORS OUT OF SPITE SAYING WE
ARE NOT GOING TO COOPERATE AND
IT'S THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT'S
PROBLEM.
>> THE FACT THAT THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT HANDLED THIS
INCOMPETENTLY, THEY HAVEN'T
GIVEN ANYONE THE STANDARDS TO
ACTUALLY BUILD THIS THING.
BILL: YOU'LL GET A REAL CONTRAST
OVERT NEXT COUPLE OF YEARS,
WHETHER THE HEALTH EXCHANGE IS A
GOOD IDEA OR A BAD IDEA, WE'LL
MEASURE IT STATE-BY-STATE.
BY THE WAY, 42% SAY IT'S GOING
TO BE A GOOD YEAR IN 2013.
41% SAY IT'S A BAD YEAR.
BOOM.
>> DO YOU THINK WE ARE A DIVIDED
COUNTRY.
BILL: RIGHT ON, SEE YOU JUAN,
SEE YOU MARY CATHERINE.
HAVE A GOOD WEEKEND.
ALISYN: WE HAVE A FEW UPDATES TO
THE BREAKING NEWS WE HAVE BEEN
REPORTED FOR THE PAST FEW
MINUTES, THAT IS A POSSIBLE
SHOOTING AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, 50,
60 MILES NORTH OF NEW YORK
CITY.
THE NEW INFORMATION THAT WE HAVE
IS THAT THE SHOOTING WAS
REPORTED AT THIS ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, KINDERGARTEN THROUGH
FOURTH AT 9:41AM, THE SCHOOL
OPENS AT 9:00AM EVERY DAY.
THIS IS ACCORDING TO STATE
POLICE.
"THE TWO TOWN B IS REPORTING
MULTIPLE POLICE AND AMBULANCES
ARE AT THE SCENE, THEY SAY THERE
ARE MULTIPLE REPORTS OF
INJURIES.
WE HAVE NOT BEEN ABLE TO CONFIRM
THIS YET.
OUR LOCAL FOX AFFILIATE SAYS
THAT CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
ARE ON THE SCENE, THEY ARE
RESPONDING TO THESE REPORTS, AND
ANOTHER DISPATCH, THE POLICE
DISPATCH SAYS THAT THIS ACTUALLY
HAPPENED OUTSIDE OF THE SCHOOL,
BUT WE UNDERSTAND THE SCHOOL IS
IN LOCKDOWN MODE, WE'VE ALSO
HEARD REPORTS OF CHILDREN BEING
LED OUT OF THE SCHOOL IN
MULTIPLE GROUPS TO A STAGING
AREA WHERE THEIR TERRIFIED
PARENTS CAN HOPEFULLY REUNITE
WITH THEM.
AGAIN, THIS IS ALL PRELIMINARY.
WE HAVE NOT BEEN ABLE TO CONFIRM
YET THAT THERE WAS A SHOOTING AT
THIS SCHOOL, BUT IT SOUNDS LIKE
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE ARE
TAKING THIS VERY SERIOUSLY AND
THEY ARE AT THE SCHOOL
SURROUNDING IT EN MASSE.
WE WILL BRING MORE OF THIS
INFORMATION AND THIS STORY TO
YOU AS SOON AS "AMERICA'S
NEWSROOM" CONTINUES.
[ Malennouncer ]
IT'S TT TIME OF YEAR AGAIN.
TIME FOR CITI PRICE REWIND.
BECAUSE YOUR DAUGHTER REALLY
WANTS THAT PINK CASTLE THING.
AND YOU REALLDON'T WANT
TO PAY MORE THAN YOU HAVE TO.
ONLY CITI PRICE REWIND
AUTOMATICALLY SEARCHES
FOR THE LOWEST PRICE.
AND IF IT FINDONE, YOU GET
REFUNDED THE DIFFERENCE.
JUST USE YOUR CITI CARD
AND REGISTER YOUR PURCHASE
ONLINE.
HAVE A SUPER SPARKLY DAY!
OK.
[ Male Announcer ] NOW ALL
YOUEED IS A MAGIC CARRIAGE.
CITI PRICE REWIND.
START SAVING
AT CITI.COM/PRICEREWIND.
CITI PRICE REWIND.
Social Security are just numbers
thinkin a budget.d...
Well, we worked hard for those
benefits.
We earned them.
And if Washington tries to cram
decisions about the future...
of these programs into a last
minute budget deal...
we'll all pay the price.
AARP is fighting to protect
seniors with responsible...
solutions that strengthen
Medicare and...
Social Security for generations
to come.
We can do better than a last
minute deal...
that would hurt all of us.
BILL: THE FOG OF BREAKING NEWS
IN SOUTHWESTERN CONNECTICUT, WE
ARE WORKING THROUGH THE STORY.
IN NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL THERE THE NEWS
CROSSED ABOUT 30 MINUTES AGO AND
WE ARE STILL TRYING TO GATHER AS
MUCH AS WE CAN FOR YOU THIS.
THIS IS WHAT WE CAN REPORT.
STATE POLICE ARE ASSISTING LOCAL
POLICE AMID REPORTS OF A SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
WE ARE GETTING WORD THROUGH THE
SUPERINTENDENT'S OFFICE THAT
REPORTS OF A SHOOTING ARE NOT
CONFIRMED.
THAT DOES NOT MEAN IT DID NOT
HAPPEN.
THE SCHOOL APPARENTLY HAS BEEN
EVACUATED WITH CHILDREN BEING
LED OUTSIDE, ANNA IS IN TOUCH
WITH THE SCHOOL AS WELL.
WHAT INFORMATION DO YOU HAVE.
>> Reporter: WE HAVE OUR
PRODUCERS ON THE PHONE TRYING TO
WORK TO GET MORE INFORMATION
ABOUT THE SHOOTING THAT DID
HAPPEN IN WESTERN CONNECTICUT
THERE IN THE TOWN OF NEWTOWN.
THESE ARE JUST REPORTS.
ALL OF THIS IS PRELIMINARY.
THERE HAVE BEEN REPORTS THAT AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
THERE WAS A SHOOTING.
THEY ARE REPORTING THAT MULTIPLE
POLICE, AMBULANCES AND EMERGENCY
CREWS ARE ON THE SCENE.
THERE ARE ALL THE AM REPORTS OF
INJURIES IN THAT AREA.
WHAT WE ARE HEARING FROM THE
SUPERINTENDENT'S OFFICE IS THAT
THEY ARE LOCKING DOWN THE
SCHOOL, JUST SIMPLY TO INSURE
THE SAFETY OF STUDENTS AND
STAFF, THEY ARE NOT, YOU KNOW,
CONFIRMING ANYTHING TO US AT THE
MOMENT, BUT WE CAN TELL YOU THAT
LOCAL POLICE ARE BEING ASSISTED
BY THE POLICE IN THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT AS WELL.
BILL: THANK YOU.
WHEN YOU GET MORE WE'LL BRING
YOU BACK ON THE AIR WORKING THAT
STORY FROM OUR NEWSROOM HERE IN
NEW YORK.
ALISYN: I KNOW NEWTOWN WELL,
THIS IS A VERY SWEET, LITTLE
PRETTY TOWN, LOTS OF CHURCHES
AND PUBLIC SQUARES, JUST A SMALL
TOWN, AGAIN ABOUT 60 MILES
NORTHEAST OF NEW YORK CITY, LOTS
OF COMMUTERS FROM NEW YORK LIVE
THERE.
THIS.
AGAIN IS ALL THE REPORTS AROUND
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, WE
UNDERSTAND IT'S A KINDERGARTEN
THROUGH FOURTH GRADE SCHOOL.
THEY START AT 9:00AM EVERY DAY
AND AT 9:41 THIS MORNING THE
NEWTOWN POLICE BEGAN GETTING
THESE CALLS.
THEY RUSHED TO THE SCENE AND
THERE ARE REPORTS OF ALL OF
THESE POLICE, AMBULANCE AND
EMERGENCY CREWS ON THE SCENE,
NOT TO SUGGEST THAT THAT MEANS
THAT THERE WAS A SHOOTING, BUT
THEN THERE ARE ALSO LOCAL
REPORTS FROM OUR LOCAL FOX
AFFILIATE, AND THE NEWTOWN BEE
WHICH I'M ASSUMING IS THE LOCAL
NEWSPAPER THAT THERE ARE
MULTIPLE INJURIES.
WE HAVE HEARD THERE ARE STAGING
AREAS OUTSIDE.
X CAWE CAN ONLY IMAGINE THAT
PARENTS WOULD BE RACING TO THE
SCHOOL TO TRY TO RECONNECT WITH
THEIR CHILDREN WHO AS WE ALSO
UNDERSTAND MAY OR MAY NOT BE
INSIDE ON LOCKDOWN AT THIS
TIME.
BILL.
BILL: YOU THINK ABOUT COLLEGES
ACROSS THE COUNTRY AND HOW THEY
HAVE CHANGED AND THEY'VE GOT
EVEN PLANS TOGETHER, CONTINGENCY
PLANS IN CASES LIKE THIS.
YOU THINK ABOUT HIGH SCHOOLS
TOO.
YOU DON'T THINK ABOUT ELEMENTARY
SCHOOLS, KINDERGARTEN THROUGH
FOURTH GRADE.
THERE IS A WEBSITE FOR SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THERE IS NO INFORMATION ON IT OF
VALUE THAT WOULD LEND ANY SORT
OF FACTUAL INFORMATION ON THE
GROUND.
THAT IS YOUR FIRST IMAGE RIGHT
NOW OUT OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
LET ME JUST CHECK THE WIRES HERE
REAL QUICK.
ALISYN: THIS IS THE FIRST
PHOTOGRAPH WE'RE GETTING FROM A
LOCAL NEWSPAPER.
YOU CAN SEE CLEARLY SOMETHING IS
HAPPENING AT THIS SCHOOL.
YELLOW POLICE TAPE SURROUND AN
AREA AND YOU SEE CROWDS
ASSEMBLED OUTSIDE.
HARD TO TELL FROM THIS VANTAGE
POINT IF THOSE ARE TEACHERS OR
PARENTS.
THEY LOOK LIKE ADULTS.
CLEARLY AUTHORITIES ARE TAKING
THIS VERY SERIOUSLY.
TO YOUR POINT, BILL YOU HOPE
THAT LOCAL POLICE STATIONS,
REGARDLESS OF HOW SMALL, BECAUSE
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT IS A SMALL
PLACE, HAVE DONE SOME OF THESE
DRILLS IN THE HORRIBLE
POSSIBILITY THAT SOMETHING LIKE
THIS COULD EVER HAPPEN IN THEIR
TOWN.
SO THEY ARE SURROUNDING THE
SCHOOL.
BILL: WE CAN ADD THIS TOO AND
THIS IS IMPORTANT INFORMATION
HERE.
THE MAN WHO ANSWERED A PHONE
WHEN FOX NEWS CALLED A MOMENT
AGO SAID THEY HAVE TWO
AMBULANCES ON THE SCENE, AND
THAT WHAT THE WHAT WATERBURY IS
SENDING PWHRAEPBS AS WELL.
THE REPORT THEY HAVE IS ONE
TEACHER HAS A FOOT INJURY AFTER
BEING SHOT IN THE FOOT.
SHE WAS TAKEN TO THE HOSPITAL.
IT IS THEIR INFORMATION THAT
POLICE ARE CLEARING THE SCENE.
SO PUT THAT TOGETHER AND TRY AND
FIGURE OUT WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
ALISYN: VERY SCARY STUFF.
WE HAVE BEEN ON THE PHONE ALSO
WITH THE NEWTOWN POLICE
DEPARTMENT AND OUR PRODUCERS
REPORT THAT IT JUST SOUNDS VERY
CHAOTIC THERE.
YOU CAN IMAGINE THEM FIELDING
ALL SORTS OF CALLS FROM OTHER
SCHOOLS IN THE AREA, FROM
PARENTS, FROM THE MEDIA WANTING
INFORMATION.
THEY ARE DOING THE BEST THEY CAN
BUT THEY DO NOT HAVE A LOT OF
INFORMATION YET, OTHER THAN TO
SAY THAT WE DO KNOW THE SCHOOL
IS ON LOCKDOWN, AND THAT KIDS
AND AT LEAST PARENTS HAVE
ASSEMBLED OUTSIDE, AND WE DON'T
KNOW THE MAGNITUDE OF THE
INJURIES OR HOW MANY THERE HAVE
BEEN.
THERE WERE INITIAL REPORTS OF
MULTIPLE INJURIES, BUT OF COURSE
IN BREAKING NEWS IT'S HARD TO
KNOW IF THOSE ARE ACCURATE.
BILL: WE DON'T HAVE THE
INFORMATION WE NEED RIGHT NOW TO
TELL YOU EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED,
BUT THE MIND RUNS WILD HERE IF
YOU HAVE A TEACHER SHOT IN THE
FOOT AND THE SUPERINTENDENT'S
SECRETARY SAYS THE REPORTS OF A
SHOOTING ARE NOT CONFIRMED.
IF THAT'S THE CASE DID THE
TEACHER SHOOT HIM OR HERSELF?
WE DON'T KNOW THE CHILDREN ARE
OUTSIDE, AND YOU CAN IMAGINE
PARENTS NOW UP AND DOWN THE
SOUTHWESTERN CONNECTICUT
CONCERNED ABOUT THIS.
ITS A BEAUTIFUL DAY IN THE
NORTHEAST AS YOU SEE FROM THE
PICTURE THERE, AND THE BEAUTIFUL
BLUE SKIES, HIGH, MID 40S TODAY,
45, 47 DEGREES IN MID DECEMBER,
WHICH IS UNHEARD OF HERE.
WE ARE WORKING THROUGH THE
STORY.
WE'LL TRY AND FIGURE OUT HOW THE
KIDS ARE DOING INSIDE THE SCHOOL
AS OUR COVERAGE CONTINUES.
ALISYN: WHEN YOU GO TO THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WEBSITE
IT JUST SAYS THAT KINDERGARTEN
HAS BEEN CANCELED.
WE'LL KEEP YOU UPDATED.
BILL: NEW INFORMATION JUST
JOINING US.
THERE IS BREAKING NEWS IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL FOR KIDS,
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADE.
THERE IS NEW INFORMATION FROM
THE HARTFORD CURRENT ON ITS
WEBSITE, THE NEWSPAPER OUT OF
HARTFORD, CONNECTICUT.
A NUMBER OF INJURED PARTIES, WE
ARE TOLD.
THE NATURE OF THE INJURIES NOT
CLEAR.
DON'T KNOW HOW SERIOUS THEY
ARE.
THERE ARE UNCONFIRMED REPORTS OF
TWO SHOOTERS, ONE STILL AT
LARGE, ONE DEAD.
IT WAS 9:40 IN THE MORNING,
ABOUT AN HOUR AND TEN MINUTES
AGO, POLICE REPORT A SHOOTER IN
THE MAIN OFFICE OF THE SCHOOL, A
PERSON IN ONE ROOM HAD, QUOTE,
NUMEROUS GUNSHOT SOUNDS.
GROUPS OF STUDENTS SAID TO BE
CRYING AND HOLDING HANDS, BEING
ESCORTED AWAY FROM THE SCHOOL BY
THEIR TEACHERS.
SOME OF THE STUDENTS APPARENTLY
ARE STILL INSIDE THE SCHOOL AS
OF 10:30 THIS MORNING, WHICH
WOULD HAVE BEEN 22 MINUTES AGO.
>> WE UNDERSTAND THE SCHOOL IS
NOW ON LOCKDOWN MODE.
WHAT YOU'RE SEEING ON YOUR
SCREEN ON THE LEFT SIDE OF YOUR
SCREEN IS THE FIRST AND ONLY, AS
FAR AS WE KNOW, PHOTO OF THE
SCENE.
THIS IS FROM THE HARTFORD
CURRENT, AND THAT ALL YOU CAN
SEE THERE OF COURSE IS THE
YELLOW POLICE CASE CORD DONG OFF
THE SCENE AND SOME ADULTS IN THE
BACKGROUND THERE, HARD TO KNOW
IF THOSE ARE PARENTS SHOWING UP
AT THE SCHOOL OR TEACHERS
ESCORTING STUDENTS OUT.
ON THE RIGHT SIDE OF YOUR SCREEN
IS OUR LOCAL FOX 5 AFFILIATE
CHOPPER HEADING TO THE SCENE TO
SEE MORE.
THIS IS NEW INFORMATION, BILL
THAT YOU JUST REPORTED.
APPARENTLY AGAIN THIS IS FROM
THE HARTFORD CURRENT, THAT THERE
WERE TWO SHOOTERS AND A PERSON
IN ONE ROOM HAD NUMEROUS GUNSHOT
WOUNDS.
THIS WAS APPARENTLY, ACCORDING
TO POLICE, THEY HAVE REPORTED
THAT A SHOOTER WAS IN THE MAIN
OFFICE OF THE SCHOOL.
WE DON'T KNOW IF THAT IS AN
EMPLOYEE OF THE SCHOOL, WE DON'T
KNOW IF IT'S A PARENT AT THE
SCHOOL, WE DON'T KNOW IF THIS IS
A STRANGER AT THE SCHOOL, BUT
THAT NUMEROUS GUNSHOT WOUNDS
WERE REPORTED.
NOW OF COURSE I MEAN IT'S JUST
SO TERRIFYING ANY TIME YOU HEAR
THAT THERE ARE GROUPS OF
STUDENTS WHO ARE TERRIFIED AND
HOLDING HANDS AND EITHER HIDING
IN THE SCHOOL OR BEING LED
OUT -- OUTSIDE OF THE SCHOOL.
BUT THEY ARE BEING ESCORTED BY
AUTHORITIES, SOMETIMES THEIR
TEACHERS.
IT'S HARD TO KNOW AGAIN WITH
BREAKING NEWS WHO EXACTLY IS
HURT AND IF THIS GUNMAN IS STILL
ON THE LOOSE AS THESE INITIAL
REPORTS ARE SUGGESTING.
BILL: NUMEROUS GUNSHOT WOUND AT
LEAST TO ONE PERSON.
IF THAT'S THE CASE AND THAT
STORY HOLDS UP THIS COULD BE A
TARGETED SHOOTING INSIDE THIS
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT NOW IN THE
TOWN OF FAIRFIELD COUNTY,
SOUTHWESTERN CONNECTICUT.
45 MILES SOUTHWEST OF HARTFORD.
60 MILES OUTSIDE OF NEW YORK
CITY.
A DECENT SIZED TOWN, POPULATION
ABOUT 27,000.
BUT THE SCHOOL DISTRICT ITSELF
HAS ABOUT 5400 KIDS.
IT'S A PRETTY LARGE DISTRICT.
THIS SCHOOL IN PARTICULAR,
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADE AS THE WNYW HELICOPTER
MOVES CLOSER TO THAT TOWN.
ALISYN: IT'S SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
ABOUT THAT TOWN IT'S A VERY,
VERY PRETTY TOWN.
IT HAS A LOT OF BEAUTIFUL TOWN
SQUARES, CHURCHES ON CORNERS
WITH PRETTY OLD STEEPLES.
PARTS OF IT ARE HISTORIC.
IT SHOWS THAT THIS SORT OF
TERROR PARENTS EXPERIENCE
EVERYWHERE, SADLY.
THIS STORY HAPPENS EVERYWHERE
AND YOU CAN JUST IMAGINE HOW
PARENTS ARE FEELING AS THEY ARE
GETTING THIS NEWS THAT SOMETHING
APPARENTLY HAS HAPPENED AT THIS
SCHOOL TODAY, AND THERE WERE
GUNSHOTS, AND THAT SOMEONE IS
HURT, BUT BEYOND THAT IT IS HARD
TO KNOW IF ALL THE STUDENTS ARE
OKAY.
WE WISH WE COULD REPORT THAT,
BUT AT THIS HOUR WE DON'T HAVE
THAT INFORMATION.
BILL: CRIME IS VERY FEW TO THIS
TOWN, VERY LOW.
ONE VIOLENT CRIMINAL OFFENSE IN
2010 IS ARE BEING REPORTED IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
OKAY, WE'RE WORKING THROUGH
THIS.
WE'LL BE ON THE PHONE WITH
POLICE AND THE SCHOOL AS WE GET
MORE INFORMATION HERE.
LET'S GET A BREAK.
BREAKING NEWS IN "AMERICA'S
NEWSROOM" AS WE WORK THROUGH THE
DEVELOPMENTS IN CONNECTICUT.
THERE'S THE SIGN TO THE BULLPEN.
HERE HE COMES.
YOU WOULDN'T WANT YOUR
DOCTOR DOING YOUR JOB,
THE PITCH!
WHOA!
SO WHY ARE YOU DOING HIS?
ONLY YR DOCTOR CAN DETERMINE
IF YOUR PERSISTENT HEARTBURN
IS ACTUALLY SOMETHING
MORE SERIOUS
LIKE ACID REFLUX DISEASE.
OVER TIME, STOMACH
ACID CAN DAMAGE
THE LINING OF YOUR ESOPHAGUS.
FOR MANY, PRESCRIPTION NEXIUM
NOT ONLY PROVIDES
24-HOUR HEARTBURN RELIEF,
BUT CAN ALSO HELP HEAL
ACID-RELATED EROSIONS IN
THE LINING OF YOUR ESOPHAGUS.
THERE IS RISK OF BONE FRACTURE
AND LOW MAGNESIUM LEVELS.
SIDE EFFECTS MAY INCLUDE
HEADACHE, ABDOMINAL
PAIN AND DIARRHEA.
CALL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY IF
YOU HAVE PERSISTENT DIARRHEA.
OTHER SERIOUS STOMACH
CONDITIONS MAY EXIST.
DON'T TAKE NEXIUM IF
YOU TAKE CLOPIDOGREL.
LET YOUR DOCTOR DO HIS JOB.
AND YOU DO YOURS.
ASK IF NEXIUM IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
IF YOU CAN'T AFFORD
YOUR MEDICATION,
ASTRAZENECA MAY BE ABLE TO HELP.
BILL: A FEW MORE PIECES OF
INFORMATION HERE WE'RE
PICKING UP LOCALLY IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THE CURRENT WEBSITE.
"HARTFORD COURANT", POLICE
SOURCES SAY THE SHOOTER IS
DEAD, AT LEAST ONE OF THEM.
EARLIER REPORTS OF A SECOND
SHOOTER ARE UNCONFIRMED.
THIS TOO, SCHOOLS IN THAT
TOWN ARE ON LOCKDOWN.
YOU CAN IMAGINE THAT THE
CASE THROUGHOUT THE TOWN OF
NEWTOWN