>> KATHERINE, CHASE, JESSIE,
JAMES, GRACE, EM LEM ILEMILIE,
JACK, NOAH, CAROLINE, JESSICA,
BENJAMIN, AVILLE, ALLISON.
GOD HAS CALLED THEM ALL HOME.
FOR THOSE OF US WHO REMAIN LET
US FIND THE STRENGTH TO CARRY ON
AND MAKE OUR COUNTRY WORTHY OF
THEIR MEMORY.
>> THIS IS A FOX NEWS ALERT.
IT STARTED BY SHOOTING HIS
MOTHER FOUR TIMES IN THE FACE
PROBABLY AS SHE SLEPT.
>> THE FEMALE THAT WAS FOUND AT
THE SECONDARY SCENE LOCATION IN
NEWTOWN HAS BEEN POSITIVELY
IDENTIFIED AS NANCY LANZA.
BIRTH DATE SEPTEMBER 6TH, 1960.
MER CAUSE OF DEATH MULTIPLE GUN
SHOT WOUNDS AND THE DEATH HAS
BEEN RULED A HOMICIDE.
>> THEN DRESSED NINJA STYLE HE
TOOK FOUR HEAVY WEAPONS PROBABLE
STASH OF HEAVY WEAPONS AND
HEADED TO THE LOCAL ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL TO IGNITE HIS PERSONAL
HOLOCAUST.
>> THE MALE SUBJECT IDENTIFIED
AS THE SHOOTER OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HAS BEEN
POSITIVELY IDENTIFIED AS ADAM
LANZA.
HE RESIDED AT THAT RESIDENCE.
>> I AM GERALDO RIVERA REPORT
LIVE ON THE DAY THE PRESIDENT OF
THE UNITED STATES CAME TO
COMFORT THIS STRICKEN
CONNECTICUT COMMUNITY RAVRAGEED
BY THE UNPRECEDENTED SLAUGHTER
THE STATE POLICE SPOKESMAN
CONFIRMED WHENEVER ADAM LANZA'S
MOTIVES THE TROUBLED 20-YEAR-OLD
BLASTED HIS WAY INTO THE SCHOOL
INTENDING TO BUTCHER AS MANY
CHILDREN AS HE COULD.
>> THE WEAPONS THAT WAS UTILIZED
MOST OF THE TIME DURING THIS
HORRIFIC CRIME WAS IDENTIFIED AS
THE BUSHMASTER AR 15 ASSAULT
TYPE WEAPON IT HAD HIGH CAPACITY
MAGAZINES AND IN ADDITION THE
SUBJECT HAD A GLOCK 10
MILLIMETER ALL WEAPONS HAD
MULTIPLE MAGAZINES AND
ADDITIONAL AMMUNITION.
>> AFTER KILLING THE HEROIC
PRINCIPAL AND FOUR OTHERS ALL
WOMEN WHO TRIED TO TOP THEM OR
SHIELD THE CHILDREN IN THEIR
CARE.
WHEN THE TINY VICTIMS IN THE
CLASSROOM LANZA USED THE ASSAULT
WEAPON TO KILL EVERY CHILD
WITHIN RANGE OF HIS RAGE.
>> THE BUSHMASTER WAS USED AS IT
WAS EXPLAINED YESTERDAY IN THE
SCHOOL IN ITS ENTIRETY AND THE
HAND GUN WAS USED TO.
>> THEN HE HEARD THE VINES COPS
APPROACHED HE D WHAT WE ONLY
WISH HE HAD DONE FIRST.
>> HIS CAUSE OF DEATH WAS GUN
SHOT WOUNDS.
HIS DEATH HAS BEEN RULED A
SUICIDE.
>> AFTER MEETING WITH THE
FAMILIES OF LANZA'S VICTIMS IN
SEPARATE CLASSROOMS IN THE LOCAL
HIGH SCHOOL THE PRESIDENT SPOKE
THIS EVENING IN A MOVING
INTERFAITH VIGIL IN THE SCHOOL
AUDITORIUM.
HERE NOW MORE OF HIS REMARKS.
>> WE GATHER HERE IN MEMORY OF
20 BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN AND 6
REMARKABLE ADULTS.
THEY LOST THEIR LIVES IN A
SCHOOL THAT COULD HAVE BEEN ANY
SCHOOL IN A QUIET TOWN FULL OF
GOOD AND DECENT PEOPLE THAT
COULD BE ANY TOWN IN AMERICA.
HERE IN NEWTOWN I COME TO OFFER
THE LOVE AND PRAYERS OF A
NATION.
I AM VERY MINDFUL THAT MERE
WORDS CANNOT MATCH THE DEPTHS OF
YOUR SORROW NOR CAN THEY HEAL
YOUR WOUNDED HEARTS.
I CAN ONLY HOPE THAT IT HELPS
FOR YOU TO KNOW THAT YOU ARE NOT
ALONE IN YOUR GRIEF.
THAT OUR WORLD, TOO, HAS BEEN
TORN APART.
THAT ALL ACROSS THIS LAND OF
OURS WE HAVE WEPT WITH YOU.
WE HOLD OUR CHILDREN TIGHT.
YOU MUST KNOW THAT WHATEVER
MEASURE OF COMFORT WE CAN
PROVIDE WE WILL PROVIDE IT.
WHATEVER PORTION OF SADNESS THAT
WE CAN SHARE WITH YOU TO EASE
THIS HEAVY LOAD, WHETHER HE G  D
GLADLY BURY.
NEWTOWN, YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
>> MEMBERS OF THE NEWS MEDIA HAD
ORIGINALLY BEEN GIVEN PERMISSION
TO BE INSIDE THE HIGH SCHOOL AT
TONIGHT'S PRAYER VIGIL BUT CTHA
CHANGED WHEN ANONYMOUS PHONE
CALL THREATEN TO DO KILL
EVERYBODY WITH A BOMB PRESUMABLY
EVERYBODY IN THE BUILDING.
>> ANY ONE THAT HARASSES,
THREATENS, OR INTICK GAMIDATES
THE INVESTIGATION UTILIZING
SOCIAL MEDIA OF ANY TYPE
RELATIVE TO THE HORRIFIC CRIME
WILL BE FULLY INVESTIGATED AND
PROSECUTED.
>> THE FIRST VICTIM 6 YEARS OLD
WILL BE TOMORROW AT THE CEMETERY
AT MONROE CONNECTICUT.
WITH MORE ON THE VICTIMS THEIR
FAMILIES AND THE PRESIDENT'S
TOUCHING REMARK LET'S GO BACK TO
NEW TOWN AND FOX NEWS
CORRESPONDENT MOLLY LION.
I HEARD SOBBING IN THE
BACKGROUND AS THE PRESIDENT WAS
READING THE NAMES OF THESE
LITTLE VICTIMS PARTICULARLY.
TELL US MORE ABOUT THEM.
WHAT HAVE YOU LEARNED NOW THAT
WE ARE IN THIS 72-HOURS
FOLLOWING THIS DEVASTATING
HORRIBLE MASSACRE.
WHAT MORE DO YOU KNOW?
>> A TREMENDOUS AMOUNT OF
SADNESS AS YOU MENTIONED,
GERALDO.
IT ALL BEGAN WE KNEW V-- THERE
WOULD BE 20 CHILDREN 6 WOMEN.
NOW THAT WE ARE LEARNING ABOUT
EACH OF THEM AND SEEING THEIR
FACES IT LOOKS MUCH MORE ROOL.
TAKE EMILIE PARKER A 6-YEAR-OLD
GIRL A BIG SISTER A BIG SMILE.
HER FATHER SAYS SHE WAS
BEAUTIFUL BLONDE AND ALWAYS
HAPPY.
HE SAYS SHE WAS A BUDDING ARTIST
WHO WOULD SPREAD HER LOVE
THROUGH DREWIAWING.
OLIVIA ENGELS THEY HAVE A
MEMORIAL FUND FILLED WITH
CHRISTMAS THEMED PHOTOS IN HER
MEMORY.
>> DANIEL BARTON 7 YEARS OLD THE
YOUNGEST CHILD OF MARK AND
JACKIE BARTON.
HE WAS A FIRST GRADER AND LOVED
TO PLAY SOCCER.
OF THE SIX WOMEN MANY ARE
HAILING AS HEROS INCLUDING A
PRINCIPAL OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY DAWN HOCHSPRUNG WHO
TRIED TO STOP THE GUNMAN.
SOMEONE PASSIONATE ABOUT
EDUCATING CHILDREN AND AMONG
MANY OF THE WOMEN THERE IN THAT
SCHOOL WHO TRIED TO SAVE THEM.
>> I NOTICE YOU HAVE GREENE ON,
I HAVE A GREEN TIE ON AND THE
PRESIDENT DID.
GREENE AND WHITE IS THE COLOR OF
THE SCHOOL.
WE ASK THAT YOU WEAR GREEN AND
WHITE TOMORROW TO COMMEMORATE
THE LIVES OF THESE YOUNG
VICTIMS.
HOW DID THE PRESIDENT'S REMARKS
PLAY THERE AT GROUND ZERO WHERE
THIS TERRIBLE ACROSS CITY WAS
COMMITTED?
>> UNDERSTANDABLY PARTICULARLY
WHEN HE WAS READING THE NAMES OF
THE VICTIMS SO MANY PEOPLE IN
THAT ROOM KNEW OF THEM KNEW
THEIR FAMILY, KNEW THEM
PERSONALLY.
SO THE REACTION WAS TEARS AND
HEARTACHE AND THE PAIN AUZ
AUDIBLE IN THAT ROOM.
THOSE ARE NAMES THAT -- NAMES WE
HEAR ALL ACROSS AMERICA AND PAIN
WRENCHING FOR THE PEOPLE WHO
HAVE SEEN THEIR FACES.
>> HER BODY WAS FOUND ON TOP OF
A WHILE OF HER CHILDREN'S LITTLE
BODIES IS REMEMBERED BY HER
FAMILY AND FRIENDS.
THE SCHOOL DID NOT HESITATE, NOT
HOCHSPRUNG, MARY SHIRLAK, VICKI
SOTO, LAUREN RUSSO, RACHEL
DEVENO AND MARY ANN MURPHY.
THEY RESPONDED IN THE WAY WE
HOPE WE WOULD RESPOND IN
TERRIFYING CIRCUMSTANCES WITH
COURAGE AND WITH LOVE.
GIVING THEIR LIVES TO PROTECT
THE CHILDREN IN THEIR CARE.
>> AS OUTRAGEOUS AS THE STORY OF
ADAM LANZA'S MASSACRE IS.
IT IS NOT AS THE PRESIDENT SAID
WITHOUT HEROS.
REMEMBERED TONIGHT BY THE
PRESIDENT BY THE THOUSANDS WHO
BLOCKED THIS NIGHT TO DOWNTOWN
NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT.
HERE IS CRAIG'S REPORT.
>> THROUGH OUT SANDY HOOK
VILLAGE RESIDENTS HAVE SET UP
TABLES THEY ARE COLLECTING
DONATIONS FOR THE FAMILIES.
THESE GUYS OVER HERE ARE GOING
FROM CAR TO CAR.
TELL ME ABOUT WHAT YOU ARE
DOING?
>> WE ARE JUST GETTING DONATIONS
FOR EVERYONE.
ALL OF THE MONEY IS GOING
DIRECTLY TO THE FAMILIES ALL OF
THE VICTIMS.
>> I WENT TO SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
>> NOW A COLLEGE STUDENT HOME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS ANDREW AND
FRIENDS ARE COLLECTING FOR
SURVIVORS OF THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL MASSACRE.
>> IT IS JUST TERRIBLE.
I JUST CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
>> SCENES LIKE THIS ARE ECHOED
ALL OVER TOWN.
GRIEF STRICKEN RESIDENTS SOME
NOT MUCH OLDER THAN THE VICTIMS
OF THIS TRAGEDY MAKING A
PILGRIMAGE TO THIS TOWN AS
PRESIDENTIAL SECURITY TEAMS
PREPARE FOR HIS MUCH ANTICIPATED
SPEECH.
>> TELL ME WHAT ARE YOU TELLING
THE CHILDREN?
>> THEY ARE TELLING US, TELLING
US THAT PEOPLE CARE BY COMING
OUT AND PRAYING TODAY.
COMING OUT AND GIVING THEIR T
TEDDY BEARS AND BEST GIFTS FOR
THE FAMILIES.
YOU COULD IMAGE THE FAMILIES
DIDN'T SEE ANYTHING TODAY.
THE FAMILIES ARE BEING TOLD THEY
ARE BEING CARED FOR AND LOVED
AND THESE KIDS ARE COMING OUT
SAYING THAT THEY MATTER.
I AM TELLING THEM THAT EVIL
NEVER WINS.
>> CARDBOARD ANGELS REPRESENTING
THE DECEASED.
CHRISTMAS TREES DECORATED WITH
TEDDY BEARS AND THE VICTIM'S
NAMES ATTRACTING VISITORS AFROM
NEAR AND FAR.
>> PEOPLE FROM ALL OVER NEW
ENGLAND, FROM NEW YORK,
MASSACHUSETTS, COMING HERE TO
PAY TRIBUTE.
THIS ONE NAMING THE NAMES OF THE
VICTIMS INCLUDING ANN MURRAY
MURPHY A TEACHER WHO GUIDE
PROTECTING HER STUDENTS.
>> WERE YOU SURPRISED HER BODY
WAS FOUND IN A WAY SHE WAS
PROTECTING THE BODIES OF THOSE
LITTLE KIDS, THE YOUNG LIVES
THAT WERE TAKEN?
>> I KNEW THAT'S HOW SHE WAS
GOING TO BE FOUND.
I KNEW SHE WOULD PROTECT.
TO ANN MARIE YOUR KIDS WERE HER
KIDS.
SHE WOULD PROTECT ANYBODY.
SO, NO, I WASN'T SURPRISED.
>> DEAR FRIENDS MICHAEL AND
MICHELLE GRILLO KNEW 52-YEAR-OLD
ANN MARY MURPHY FOR 16 YEARS.
WHAT DOES SHE LEAVE BEHIND?
>> A BEAUTIFUL FAMILY OF FOUR
CHILDREN AND A HUSBAND THAT IS
DEDICATED TO HER AND HER FAMILY.
WE ARE SO SORRY FOR THEIR LOSS.
>> AND THEY ARE HERE TO HELP.
>> ANN MARIE'S FAMILY IS VERY
PRECIOUS TO ME.
THEY HAVE TWO CHILDREN THAT ARE
OUT OF COLLEGE NOW ONE IN
COLLEGE AND A YOUNG DAUGHTER
THAT IS A SENIOR IN HIGH SCHOOL
THAT IS GOING TO NEED THE
COMMUNITY TO HELP AND STEP UP
AND STAND BEHIND HER AND HELP
HER AS SHE GOES THROUGH THE NEXT
YEARS.
>> LOOKING DOWN THE ROUGH ROAD
AHEAD THE GRILLOS'S HAVE SET UP
A FUND TO HELP HER 18-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHTER WHO IS THEIR DAUGHTER'S
BEST FRIEND.
>> TELL ME WHAT YOU ARE DOING?
>> I HAVE COMMITTED TO THE
MURPHY FAMILY WE ARE GOING TO
HELP WITH THEIR YOUNGEST
DAUGHTER'S COLLEGE EDUCATION.
ANNE MARIE HAS BEEN DEDICATED TO
THE FAMILY AND THE COMMUNITY HER
ACTIONS WERE NOT A SURPRISE AT
ALL.
IT'S THE FACT THAT SHE WOULD
STEP UP AND TRY TO PROTECT THE
CHILDREN BARACK OBAMA HERSELF IS
WHAT ANNE MARIE WOULD DO.
>> I KNOW EVERYONE IS STILL IN
SHOCK.
TELL ME WHAT KIND OF I AM FACT
THIS HAS HAD ON YOU AND THIS
COMMUNITY.
>> LIKE I SAID WE ARE IN SHOCK.
YOU WANT BELIEVE YOU WOULD LOSE
THESE PRECIOUS LIVES.
ANN MARIE THESE CHILDREN PRO
HAVEN'T EX PEER -- WHO HAVEN'T
EXPERIENCED LIFE YET.
WE NEED TO FIND A WAY TO STOP
THE CENTER LINES.
IT HAS TONED.
>> TO THE GURILOO'S THEIR
PRECIOUS FRIEND WAS TAKEN FAR
TOO SOON BUT ANNE MARIE'S
ACTIONS, HER SACRIFICE WILL
ALWAYS BE REMEMBERED.
>> SHE IS A HERO.
THAT GIVES US SOMETHING TO HOLD
ON TO.
I THINK THAT IS WHAT I AM
HOLDING ON TO RIGHT NOW IS THAT
SHE IS A HERO.
>> SHE WILL ALWAYS BE REMEMBERED
THAT WAY.
>> RIGHT.
>> IT WILL PROVIDE THE FAMILY
WITH A LOT OF COMFORT KNOWING
WHAT A HERO SHE IS.
IT'S GOING TO TAKE A LONG TIME
TO HEAL THESE WOUNDS.
>> IT WILL TAKE THE COUNTRY A
LONG TIME TO HEAL FROM THESE
WOUNDS.
THIS IS FAR BEYOND NEW THOUN.
>> IT IS, HE IS RIGHT ABOUT THAT
CRAIG, AB WHY YOU WILL.
A LOT OF PEAS PEOPLE HAVE
COLLEGE AGED KIDS.
SHE WAS ONE OF THE INCOME LEARN
HERS, THEY SET UP A FUND?
>> IT IS CALLED THE FINNEY
ADKINSON SCHOLARSHIP FUND.
IT ALREADY RAISED 50,000 DOLLARS
FOR OTHER CAUSES IN NEW TOWN NOW
YOU HAVE TO HELP THE FAMILY ANN
MARIE MURPHY YOU CAN FIND OUT
MORE AT WWW.BENNY AT KIN TON
GULF.COM.
SOUNDS LIKE A GOOD DAYS MOO ME
GERALDO.
BENNY AXI
BENNY GOLFED, GOV.
>> THIS IS THE 4TH TIME THE
PRESIDENT HAS BEEN CALLED ON TO
RESPOND TO A MASS DUR DER.
UP NEXT, WE WILL FIND OUT FROM
MIKE KOBE BEN WHAT HAPPENED WITH
THAT ON NONMOUSE PHONE CALL.
THE PRESIDENT AS HEALER IN CHIEF
AFTER THIS.
>> THE SHOOTING AFTER THE
THEATER AND TONIGHT THE
PRESIDENT TOUCHED THEIR HEARTS.
>> SINCE I HAVE BEEN PRESIDENT
THIS IS THE 4TH TIME WE HAVE
COME TOGETHER TO COMFORT A
GRIEVING COMMUNITY TORN APART BY
MASS SHOOTINGS.
FOURTH TIME WE CONSOLED
SURVIVORS AND FOURTH TIME WE CON
SOULED THE FAMILIES OF VICTIMS.
IN BETWEEN THERE HAVE BEEN AN
ENDLESS SERIES OF DEAD LIGHT
SHOOTINGS ACROSS THE COUNTRY
ALMOST DAILY REPORTS OF VICTIMS
MANY OF THEM CHILDREN, IN SMALL
TOWNS AND BIG CITIES ALL ACROSS
AMERICA.
VIC TIMES WHOSE MUCH OF THE TIME
THEIR ONLY FAULT WAS BEING IN
THE WRONG PLACE AT THE WRONG
TIME.
WE CAN'T TOLERATE THIS ANY MORE.
THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
TO END THEM WE MUST CHANGE.
>> BUT EXACTLY WHAT ARE WE GOING
TO CHANGE?
ARE WE GOING TO CHANGE THE GUN
CONTROL LAWS?
ARE WE GOING TO CHANGE THE
ENTERTAINMENT INDUSTRY AND
VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES?
ARE WE GOING TO CHANGE THE
MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEM?
WE WILL DISCUSS THAT AS THE
PROGRAM PROGRESSES TONIGHT.
RIGHT NOW FOR MORE REACTION
LET'S GO TO MIKE TOBIN IN
NEWTOWN.
WHAT'S YOUR HEADLINE?
WHAT IS YOUR TAKE AWAY, WHAT ARE
YOU FEELING?
>> THE HEADLINE IS THE ATF IS
CONFIRMING ADAM LANZA AT ONE
POINT WENT TO A LOCAL SHOOTING
RANGE.
THEY ARE NOT CONFIRMING HE FIRED
ANY TIME WHILE HE WAS THERE.
NANCY LANZA AT ONE POINT VISITED
A SHOOTING RANGE.
THAT SQUARES UP WITH THE FAMILY.
INDIVIDUALLY THEY WERE AT A GUN
RANGE AT SOME POINT FOR THE
CONFIRMING WE EVER WENT
TOGETHER.
THIS IS AN ONGOING INVESTIGATION
SCOURING MORE THAN 80 WHNSED GUN
FACILITY.
S.
HE CARRIED WITH HIM AN ARSENAL,
A BUSH HASTER AR 145 COUPLED UP
WITH HIGH CAPACITY MAGAZINES
THAT WERE INTERCHANGED HE WEAR
IDEA A 6 OR 9 MILL MERRER AND A
GLOCK.
A SINGLE BULLET HE PUT HIS IN
OWN HEAD.
THE FOURTH VICTIM WAS LEFT OUT
IN THE CAR IN THE PARKING LOT.
AN IMPORTANT INVESTIGATION.
>> ANY IDEA WHY THEY DIDN'T HAVE
ANY --
>> THERE WAS A TALK SHE LIVED IN
THE BIG HOUSE BY HERSELF.
SOME SHE GREW UP IN THE COUNTRY
GUNS WERE PART OF HER LIFE.
WE KNOW SHE WENT TO A LOCAL
BOUGHTERING HOLE AND SHE TOOK
PRIDE IN THAT GUN COLLECTION.
ALMOST AS THINKING WHY THOSE   N
IRN>> WE DON'T KNOW THAT SHE WAS
ASLEEP AT THE TIME.
BUT THE INFORMATION WE HAVE
COMING OUT O SHE WAS
IN BED WEARING PAJAMAS SHOT FOUR
TIMES IN THE HEAD.
>> IN TERMS OF THE ASSAILANT AS
HE GOES IN IT IS PRETTY CLEAR
NOW HE USED THE AR 15 TO BLAST
THE CLASS AND WALK THROUGH INTO
THE SCHOOL.
>> THAT IS THE INDICATION THAT
HE CAULKED IN, HE COULD HAVE
GONE A NUMBER OF DIRECTIONS AND
WENT TO THE DIRECTION OF TWOEZ
TWO CLASSROOMS.
THE AREA WAS CONTAINED THOUGH
THE HALLWAY AND THE TWO CLASSES.
DAWN HUKT TRIES TO JUMP ON HIM.
>> DOWN HOOK SKROM.
ONE WAS DISCHARRING ROUNDS.
SO RAPIDLY.
IT WAS A TEM SEMI.
HE FIRED EACH GROUND HE PULLED
THE KRIGER.
>> AS THE DE TATE THIS
HORRENDOUS SIGN FROM PIHAPPENIN
GWEN.
VIDEO GAMES AND MENTAL HEALTH
SYSTEM.
IS IT EVEN REMOTELYYYYYY
foxnews.com.
>> TIME FOR THE PRESIDENT TO
STAND UP AND LEAD AND TELL THE
COUNTRY WHAT TO DO NOT GO TO
CONGRESS AND SAY WHAT DO YOU
GUYS WANT TO DO.
THIS SHOULD BE HIS NUMBER ONE
AGENDA.
HE'S THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES.
SOMETHING LIKE 48,000 AMERICANS
WILL BE KILLED WITH ILLEGAL
GUNS.
THAT IS ROUGHLY THE NUMBER OF
AMERICANS KILLED IN THE WHOLE
VIETNAM WAR.
NO SINGER LAW NO SET OF LAWS CAN
ELIMINATE EVIL FROM THE WORLD OR
PREVENT EVERY SENSELESS ACT OF
VIOLENCE IN OUR SOCIETY.
THAT CAN'T BE AN EXCUSE FOR AN
ACTION.
IN THE COMING WEEKS I WILL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT, MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS, PARENTS
AND EDUCATOR IN AN EFFORT AIMED
AT PREVENTING MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS.
BECAUSE WHAT CHOICE DO WE HAVE?
>> WHAT IS HE TALKING ABOUT?
I MEAN I MENTIONED THE NEED TO
EXAMINE OUR MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEM
SOMETHING I KNOW ABOUT.
MAYBE EVEN TACKLE THE TRICKY
ISSUE OF THE ROLE VIOLENCE VIDEO
GAMES PLAYED IN THE HEINOUS
CRIMES.
IN THE MEANTIME WHAT DO YOU
THINK ABOUT MY IDEA THAT WE HAVE
AT LEAST ONE ARMED PERSON EITHER
A COP OR TRAINED LICENSED
SECURITY GUARD IN EVERY SCHOOL
OVER A CERTAIN SIZE.
LET'S ASK KEN TRUMP PRESIDENT OF
THE YOU NATIONAL SCHOOL SAFETY
AND SECURITY SERVICES.
ROBERT A. JACKS FORMER LAPD
DETECTIVE.
HERE IN NEW YORK WITH ME CHIEF
MCNAMARA.
WHAT DO YOU THINK, CHIEF?
>>> OO WE SHOULD HAVE OUR EYE ON
THE IRRESPONSIBILISSUE.
NOT ONE SINGLE WITH THE ABILITY
TO DO IT.
IS THAT NOT AN OPTION?
WHEN WHICH LOOKS AT MORE SCHOOL
RESOURCE OFFICERS IN THE HIGH
SCHOOL?
OBVIOUSLY NOW AS THE VIOLENCE
TENDS TO TRICKLE DOWN IN THE
SCHOOL.
THAT'S ONE OPTION.
>> I AM TALKING ABOUT DOING
SOMETHING RIGHT NOW.
MANY COPS DURING A TYPICAL
WEEKDAY IN NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT?
>> FOUR OR FIVE.
>> WHY CAN'T ONE COP STAY IN A
PATROL CAR OUTSIDE OF SCHOOL?
>> LET'S FACE IT LAW ENFORCEMENT
THE DEMANDS ON LAW ENFORCEMENT
ARE INCREASING.
WHEN YOU DON'T HAVE THE
RESOURCES TO DEVOTE TO ONE
SCHOOL.
>> KEN TRUMP DO YOU HAVE AN
OPINION ON THAT?
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
>> ALL OF THE IDEAS STARTING TO
TRICKLE OUT OF WASHINGTON AND
SOME OF THE BROADER THINGS THAT
YOU TALKED ABOUT.
WE HAVE SCHOOL RESEARCH OFFICERS
IN A NUMBER OF OUR SCHOOLS.
WE THE COPS AND SCHOOLS PROGRAM
FUNDED.
IT HAS BEEN ELIMINATED.
IT WAS ELIMINATED AND THE U.S.
DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION TWO
YEARS AGO ELIMINATED COMPLETELY.
THEY PROVIDED SECURITY
EQUIPMENT.
I UNDERSTAND THAT HASN'T BEEN
FOUNDED THIS YEAR.
I HAVE TO POINT AFTER WONDERING
IN THE LAST COUPLE DAYS LIKE YOU
IN NEWTOWN.
MY QUESTION IS DO WE NEED TO DO
SOMETHING NEW AND GO BACK TO THE
FUNDAMENTALS GO BACK TO THE
THINGS THERE AND FIND OUT WHY
PEOPLE STOP THAT WHEN THERE
WASN'T A CRISIS IN THE
HEADLINES.
>> DO YOU THINK THE PRESIDENT
HAS FAILED DO YOU THINK HE HAS
EARNED WHAT HE GOT FROM THE
BRADY GROUP THAT WANTS TO BAN
ASSAULT WEAPONS.
>> I THINK INSIDE THE BELTWAY
FAILED AS A WHOLE WITH CONGRESS
AND THE ADMINISTRATION THEY
STOPPED THE SCHOOLS ALL OF THESE
OTHER PROGRAMS GERALDO.
MY THING IS ONE AGAIN CHIEF SAID
ONE THING IS NOT TO SECURE IT.
THEY POLITICIZE IT RIGHT AWAY.
TAKE THE THINGS WE KNOW WORK WHY
DO WE CUT THEM AND WHY DO THEY
ALLOW THAT IN THE FIRST PLACE.
MY FIRST QUESTION IS TO TAKE A
LOOK AT YOUR VOTING RECORD ASK
YOURSELF DID YOU VOTE TO LUM
NATE THOSE RESOURCES.
I AM NOT SUGGESTING IT WILL BE
THE CURE BUT WHAT ARE YOU TAKING
THAT ARE USEFUL TO HELP THEM
PREPARED.
NEWTOWN HAD A SCHOOLS GRANT BACK
WHEN IT ORIGINATED FOR A SCHOOL
OFFICER, WHY DID YOU ALLOW THAT
TO GO.
WE ARE A ROLLER-COASTER SOCIETY
PUBLIC POLICY AND PUBLIC
FUNDING.
IF IT HAPPENED TODAY FINE.
6 MONTH DOWN THE ROAD IT FALLS
ON THE BACK BURNERS WE SCRATCH
OUR HEADS WHEN THIS HAPPENS AND
SAY HOW DID IT HAPPEN.
I AM FRUSTRATED 25 YEARS IN THIS
BUSINESS YOU SEE THE SAME THING
OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
WE DON'T NEED A COMMISSION TO
FIGURE THIS OUT.
MANY OF THE THINGS WE NEED TO DO
WHY AREN'T WE GETTING IT DONE.
>> I HEAR YOU AND I TOTALLY
AGREE.
WE ARE SO FICKLE THE SPOTLIGHT
IS ON SOMETHING THE LEGISLATURES
RESPOND WHEN THE SPOTLIGHT IS ON
AS SOON AS THE NEXT THING DIE
VERLTS OUR ATTENTION THE
LEFT-HANDERS ARE ON THE HOOK.
>> WHAT DO YOU THINK?
>> GERALDO FIRST THING IS THE
POLICE THEMSELVES RARELY WOULD
THEY BE ABLE TO NEGATE A
SITUATION LIKE THIS BY JUST
RESPONDING.
TOO MUCH TIME GOES BY.
>> IN 90 SECONDS THE BAD GUY IS
IN THERE KILLING KIDS.
TOUGH STOP IT IN THE FIRST 5
SECONDS.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> SECONDLY THE POLICE HAVE
LIMITED RESOURCES.
I AM NOT QUITE SURE THAT TAKING
FROM THE POLICE WITH THEIR
SECU
CURRENT NUMBERS.
I MIGHT SUGGEST EACH COMMUNITY
WOULD HAVE TO DECIDE.
I WOULD HAVE A READY POOL OF
TRAINED PEOPLE.
BUT YOU HAVE GOT ALL OF THESE
HIGHLY DECORATED VALUED COMBAT
VETERANS IN IRAQ AND AFGHANISTAN
WHO ARE IN NEED OF JOBS.
WHO BETTER TO PROTECT OUR
CHILDREN THAN THE PEOPLE WHO
PROTECTED AND SAVED OUR LIVES ON
THE FRONT LINE.
>> WE HAVE 117,000 SCHOOLS IN
THE COUNTRY.
WE HAVE TO STOP THE VICIOUS
CYCLE WHERE THE CRISIS HAPPENS
WE TALK ABOUT IT FOR A WHILE AND
THEN WE GO BACK TO NORMAL.
EVERY DAY IN THIS COUNTRY THEY
ARE THINKING SAFETY.
IF THE MOFTMENT IS FOR ARMED
PEOPLE IN SCHOOLS -- I DON'T
KNOW IF THAT'S A GOOD IDEA.
>> I JUST WANT ONE, ONE PERSON A
SUPERINTENDENT, THE HEAD
JANITOR, IT COULD BE THE FIZZ ED
TEACHER, IT COULD BE A UNIFORMED
SECURITY GUY IT COULD BE THE
HISTORY TEACHER.
JUST ONE.
>> SO YOU ARE NOT SITTING DUCKS
WHEN YOU HAVE A MASSACRE GOING
ON.
>> NOBODY WANTS TO SEE THAT.
THAT IS A GOOD DEBATE TO HAVE.
I WOULD HAVE TO UNDERSTAND IT
BETTER TO UNDERSTAND THE
BACKGROUND ON THESE PEOPLE AND
WHO IS GOING TO CARRY THE
FIREARM.
MORE IMPORTANT THING TO SAY IS
WE NEED TO DIALOGUE WE CAN'T
KEEP HAVING THESE THINGS AP HEN.
FORMER RESPECT DETECT GIVE BOB
JACKS.
>> SPEAKER OF THE HOUSE JOHN
BAYLOR JUST SWITCHING GEARS.
I WILL RAISE THE RATE.
I AM WITCH PEOPLE.
WAIT UNTIL YOU HEAR THAT.
IS HILLARY CLINTON REALLY SO
INJURED SHE WON'T BE ABLE TO
TESTIFY ABOUT AGAIN ZI.
THOSE STORIES AND MORE NEXT.
>> ADDS WE REMEMBER THE 20 KIDS
THE 6 ADULTS BLAMED IN THE
SCHOOL IN CONNECTICUT IT IS HARD
TO REMEMBER THE FACT THAT 17
DAYS AWAY FROM WHAT WE WERE
TALKING ABOUT LAST WEEK FALLING
OFF THE FISCAL CLIFF.
IT IS HARDLY BEING MENTIONED
RIGHT NOW.
LATE THIS AFTERNOON WORD LEAKED
IN WASHINGTON THAT THE
REPUBLICAN SPEAKER OF THE HOUSE
JOHN BOEHNER AGREED TO HAVE
TAXES TO GO UP FOR TOP EARNERS
FROM THE 35-36 PERCENT.
I THINK IT'S 36 PERCENT.
ONLY THOSE MAKING OVER 1 MILLION
A YEAR NOT THE 250,000 A YEAR
THE PRESIDENT IS REQUESTING.
KIRSTEN POWERS FOX NEWS
POLITICAL ANALYST JOINS US AS
ALICE STEWART REPUBLICAN
STRATEGIST WHO COVERED THE JONES
BOROUGH ARKANSAS SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
YOU REMEMBER THAT ONE ABOUT 15
YEARS AGO WHEN MIKE HUCKABEE WAS
THE GOVERNOR.
WE ARE HERE WITH BRET BAIER
EARLIER.
YOU WANT TO COMMENT ON THE
PRESIDENT'S SPEECH ABOUT THE
POLITICAL NATURE OF IT?
SOUNDED LIKE IT WAS FULL OF
SOMETHING YOU DIDN'T KNOW QUITE
WHAT.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING WITH THIS?
>> I REALLY HAVE TO DISAGREE
WITH PEOPLE WHO CALL IT
POLITICAL THAT YOU DON'T THINK
YOU CAN TOLERATE IT ANY MORE.
THEY ARE SAYING NOWHERE THEY
ALLOW THINGS TO GO ON.
THE PARENTS ESPECIALLY.
>> YOU GO HOPEFULLY SAYING A
COMMISSION ON GUN VIOLENCE AND
LOOKING AT THE DIFFERENT THINGS
THAT ARE FEEDING INTO IT WHETHER
IT IS MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES,
WHETHER IT'S THE AVAILABILITY OF
SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPONS.
THEY HAVE MASS KILLINGS AND
LOOKING AT THE DIFFERENT ASPECTS
NOT JUST GUN CONTROL.
>> I CAN DO WITHOUT ASSAULT
WEAPONS BEING AVAILABLE TO EVERY
TOM, DICK, HARRY AND ADAM.
JONESBOROS HAPPENS THEY GO AWAY
AND THEY KEPT ONGOING BACK.
>> THERE IS A LOT OF
SIMILARITIES CHILDREN, WE SAW
PARENTS STRUGGLING TO FIND
ANSWERS FOR THIS.
THEY HAVE SIMILAR ISSUES WITH
THIS.
OR SHELL SHOCKED AFTER THAT.
I HAVE TO DISAGREE WITH THE
PERSON IN THAT THE PRESIDENT'S
SPEECH WAS HIGHLY POLITICAL.
SPEAKING FROM THE HEART AS A
FATHER EXPRESSING HIS SYMPATHIES
I DO LIKE WHAT HE SAID TO WHAT
DEGREE WE CAN SHARE IN YOUR PAIN
TO EASE YOUR BURDEN.
THAT WAS IMPORTANT.
IT SHIFTED IN WHAT DO WE NEED TO
DO HERE.
WE NEED TO DO SOMETHING.
HOPEFULLY IT DOESN'T ZERO ONLY
IN ON GUN CONTROL.
IT'S NOT THE ONLY ISSUE.
THAT PERSON SAID THERE'S ALSO
THE MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES IT IS
VERY IMPORTANT IT CANNOT
DISREGARD THE INFLUENCE OF THE
ENTERTAINMENT INDUSTRY IN
SITUATIONS INVOLVING MASS
SHOOTINGS AND TELEVISION AND
VIDEO GAMES THEY HAVE A BIG
IMPACT ON IT.
A OO THE BOEHNER PROPOSAL IT
GOES UP ONLY IF YOU MAKE A
MILLION OR MORE.
>> I THINK THAT THAT WOULD BE A
GREAT DEAL IF THAT'S WHAT HE IS
WILLING TO DO.
THEY ARE ON THE LEFT WHICH IS
IMPORTANT A LOT OF PEOPLE SAY
WHAT DOES HE CARE?
THEY HAVE TO GET IT THROUGH
CONGRESS.
THE ANSWER WOULD BE HE'S GOING
TO HAVE TO BE RESPONSIVE TO
THAT.
THEY WANT TO SEE BECAUSE THE
PRESIDENT HAS CAVE THE ON THE
ISSUE IN THE PAST IN THE LEFT
THEY WANT TO SEE THE TAX RATE
GOING UP ON EVERYBODY OVER 250.
I PERSONALLY THINK THAT THAT IS
A GREAT DEAL IF YOU CAN GET 39
PERCENT ON ANYBODY OVER A
MILLION.
>> ME, TOO.
>> I TELL YOU WHAT, I WILL LET
YOU RESPOND ON THAT.
PLUS LADIES AND GENTLEMEN THERE
ARE SOME ACTUALLY SAYING THAT
HILLARY CLINTON IS FAKING HER
INJURY TO AVOID TESTIFYING ABOUT
BENGHAZI GATE.
YOU WILL HEAR FROM A FORMER U.N.
AMBASSADOR AFTER THIS.
>> THEY TESTIFIED SHE HAS EVERY
EXPECTATION THAT SHE WILL BE
TESTIFYING.
UNFORTUNATELY AS YOU KNOW SHE
HAS ALREADY STATED SHE WILL BE
STEPPING DOWN.
THERE ARE PRETTY GOOD REPORTS
THAT SENATOR KERRY WHO IS
HEADING THE SENATE FOREIGN
RELATIONS COMMITTEE WILL BE
TAKING HER SPOT.
I FEAR BECAUSE OF THE SHUFFLE
THAT IS GOING ON WE MAY NOT BE
ABLE TO HEAR FROM SECRETARY
CLINTON ON THE BENGHAZI
TERRORIST ATTACK.
WE WILL BE A POOR NATION FOR IT.
>> THIS IS A FOX NEWS ALERT
REPUBLICANS CRYING FOUL AS
SECRETARY HILLARY CLINTON
SUFFERING FROM THE AFTERMATH OF
A CONCUSSION SHE WILL NOT BE
TESTIFYING ABOUT AGABENGHAZI AF
ALL.
SHE WILL BE LEAVING AFTER THE
APPOINTMENT OF SENATOR JOHN
KERRY TO REPLACE HER.
THE FEAR OF REPUBLICANS IS THEY
WILL NEVER GET TO HEAR SECRETARY
CLINTON'S VERSION OF THE TRAGIC
EVENTS IN LIBYA FORMER
AMBASSADOR TO UNITED NATIONS
RICHARD WILLIAMSON DO YOU, IS
THAT ACCURATE AMBASSADOR?
>> I THINK THAT'S AN OVER
STATEMENT.
WE ALL HAVE TO HAVE SYMPATHY.
I THINK THE CONCERN IS TWO
FACTORS HAVE TO BE ANSWERED.
THE FIRST TIME IN 32 YEARS AN
AMERICAN AMBASSADOR WAS KILLED
IN A TERRORIST ATTACK AS WELL AS
THE OTHER AMERICANS.
WE HAVE TO UNDERSTAND WHY THE
STATE DEPARTMENT FAILED TO
PROVIDE ADEQUATE SECURITY AND
THEN SECURITIONDLY IT WAS EVIDE
THE TERRORIST STRATEGY OF
TARGETING KILLINGS OF AL QAEDA
HAS FAILED THAT AL QAEDA IS VERY
ACTIVE IN NORTHERN AFRICA.
THOSE ARE THE TWO ISSUES.
>> DO YOU THINK SHE IS LYING
ABOUT BEING SICK AND HAVING A
CONCLUSION?
>> NO, I WOULDN'T SAY THAT.
I WOULD SAY THAT IT WOULD BE
INAPPROPRIATE FOR HER TO LEAVE
OFFICE ABOUT AHEARING BEFORE
CONGRESS.
THERE IS TIME FOR THAT AND I
HOPE SHE DOES.
>> YOU STILL THINK THAT SHE
SHOULD AND YOU BELIEVE HER
EXPLANATION OF HER MALTY AND HER
REASONS FOR NOT TESTIFYING NOW.
>> I HAVE NO REASON TO QUESTION
HER WORD.
WHAT I DO QUESTION IS THE DELAYS
OF THE STONE WALLING ON BENGHAZI
SO LONG.
NOW WE HAVE TO GET THE STORY.
WE WILL HAVE HEARINGS THIS WEEK.
THERE WILL BE MORE HEARINGS
HOPEFULLY SECRETARY CLINTON WILL
MAKE SURE SHE TESTIFYS TO
CONGRESS AND THE AMERICAN PEOPLE
OF THE DETAILS OF FAILURE OF
STATE DEPARTMENT SECURITY AND
THE ADEQUACY OF POLICY ON
TEARRISM.
>> IN LITTLE ROCK TONIGHT WHAT
DO YOU THINK?
>> I HOPE SECRETARY CLINTON HAS
A GOOD NOTE FROM HER DOCTOR.
BAD ENOUGH FOR THE OWE BAM PAW
CAMPAIGN TO PUT AMBASSADOR RICE
ON THERE SPEAKING ON MORNING
SHOWS GIVING THEM DENY ABILITY
AS SHE HAD NOTHING TO DO WITH
BENGHAZI BUT NOW WE HAVE THE
THEM ASKING JOHN KERRY TO ANSWER
QUESTIONS CLINTON SHOULD BE
DOING.
THEY MISLED THE AMERICAN PEOPLE
AND MISLED THE PRESS.
THE TRUTH IS WE HAVE FOUR DEAD
AMERICANS AND THEIR FAMILIES
DESERVE TO KNOW HOW IN THE WORLD
THE AMERICAN GOVERNMENT COULD
HAVE LET THIS HAPPEN.
>> YOU THINK IN THE NFL WHEN
THEY DOO A TIME-OUT AND THE
OTHER PEOPLE LINES UP IN A
FORMATION THAT IS STRANGE AND
THEY ARE AFRAID THAT THEY ARE
NOT PREPARED FOR IT.
SOME GUY PULLS DOWN MAKES BELIEF
HE HURT HIS ANKLE OR SOMETHING
THEY HAVE TO PAUSE FOR THE
STRETCHERS TO COME OUT OR THE
TRAINERS TO LOOK AT IT?
DO YOU THINK THIS IS WHAT THAT
IS?
>> I HAVE NO EVIDENCE THAT THAT
IS THE CASE.
I JUST DON'T THINK THAT THE IDEA
THAT BECAUSE SHE HAS A
CONCUSSION SHE IS NOT WORKING TO
CANCEL THE TRIP SHE IS NOT
WILLING TO TESTIFY ADDS UP.
I AM SURE CONGRESS IS HAPPY TO
REARRANGE HAVE HER COME AND
TESTIFY WHENEVER WOULD WORK FOR
HER.
NOT GOING TO BE OUT OF WORK FOR
THE NEXT COUPLE OF MONTHS.
IT JUST DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
FURTHERMORE EVEN IF IT WAS AFTER
SHE LEFT THEY DON'T BAR HER FROM
KNOWING HOW IT HAPPENED AND WHY
THIS TRAGEDY OCCURRED AND WHAT
THE DEPARTMENT PLAYS IN NOT
PROVIDING TO SECURITY AND SO
FORTH.
>> SO WE SUSPEND OUR USUAL
DISBELIEF WHEN A COINCIDENCE IS
CONVENIE
CONVENIENT?
>> I AM NOT GOING TO ACCUSE HER
OF LYING.
>> ME EITHER.
>> SHE SAID SHE FAINTED AND HAS
A CONCLUSION.
>> NO.
I BELIEVE THAT PART.
>> I JUST DON'T THINK SHE SHOULD
BE ALLOWED TO NOT TESTIFY.
THIS IS ABSURD THIS IDEA -- BUY
THE IDEA SHE CAN'T EVER TESTIFY
ON THIS BECAUSE SHE IS ILL
DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
>> SO IS IT POSSIBLE, THOUGH,
YOU HAVE THE INAUGURATION YOU
HAVE THE HOLIDAYS THAT SHE WILL
NEVER TESTIFY?
>> I GUESS IT'S POSSIBLE BUT
THERE'S NO REASON FOR IT.
>> THEY CAN ARRANGE IT AROUND
HER SCHEDULE.
>> AMBASSADOR?
>> GERALDO, CONGRESS WILL COME
BACK IN SESSION IN JANUARY PRIOR
TO THE INAUGURAL.
PRESUMING THAT THE PRESIDENT
NOMINATES SENATOR KERRY THEY
WILL BE HEARING THE VOTE ON THAT
THAT MAY BE DONE BY
JANUARY 20TH.
THERE WILL BE A COUPLE OF WEEKS
WHERE CONGRESS IS IN SESSION
HOPEFULLY THE SECRETARY WILL
UNDERSTAND IT AS PART OF HER
RESPONSIBILITY THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE TO COME UP AND EXPLAIN
WHY THEY FAILED IN SECURITY WHY
OUR STRATEGY ON TERRORISM IS
FAILING.
>> AMBASSADOR RICHARD
WILLIAMSON.
FINALLY AS WE END TONIGHT'S SHOW
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN I WANT YOU
TO PLAY A VERY UNUSUAL CLIP FROM
"SATURDAY NIGHT LIVE".
THEY MAKE FUN OF EVERYTHING AND
EVERYBODY.
LAST NIGHT THEY WERE SINCERE AND
THEY PLAYED A VERY STRAIGHT
TRIBUTE TO ALL OF THE VICTIMS OF
THE NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT
MASSACRE.
THOSE LITTLE CHILDREN.
AS I SAY GOOD NIGHT TO EVERYBODY
AND HAVE A GREAT WEEK AND PLEASE
HUG YOUR CHILDREN HERE FROM
SATURDAY NIGHT LIVE.
♪ SILENT NIGHT
♪ HOLY SNINIGHT ♪
♪ ALL IS CALM
♪ ALL IS BRIGHT
♪ ROUND YOUNG VIRGIN MOTHER AND
CHILD ♪
♪ HOLY INFANT SO TENDER AND MILD
♪
♪ SLEEP IN HEAVENLY PEACE