WHERE I WAS TOSSING AND TURNING,
IT'S AN EMOTIONAL THING, SEEING
THE RUSH OF THE PARENTS TO THE
SCHOOL AND SEEING SOME OF THE
PARENTS HUGGING THEIR KIDS AND
SOME OF THEM ARE NOT WALKING
OUT.
I THINK LIMITING THE TV AND THE
EXPOSE TORT KIDS IS IMPORTANT.
GIVING THEM LOVE.
IT'S CALM, COURAGE AND CARE.
AND WE'LL GET THROUGH THIS
TOGETHER.
>> JAMIE: WE DOLL ALL OF THAT.
DOCTORS, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> ERIC: THANK YOU.
>> HAVE A GOOD WEEK.
>> ERIC: YOU TOO.
>> JAMIE: WE BEGIN WITH A FOX
NEWS ALERT, AWAITING A NEWS
CONFERENCE FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WITH THE VERY
LATEET -- LATEST ON THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING, COMING TO GRIPS WITH
THE SENSELESS TRAGEDY.
LOCAL AND FEDERAL INVESTIGATORS
HAVE FANNED OUT ACROSS THE
STATE, LOOKING FOR CLUES.
PRESIDENT OBAMA ALSO PREPARING
TO ATTEND AN INTERFAITH VIGIL
OFFERING, HEALING AS WELL TO A
GRIEF-STRICKEN NATION.
THAT'S WHERE WE ARE ALL TODAY.
THIS IS A BRAND-NEW HOUR INSIDE
AMERICA'S NEWS HEADQUARTERS.
>> ERIC: AND GOOD MORNING.
INVESTIGATORS ARE OF COURSE,
RIGHT NOW, TRYING TO PAINT A
MORE COMPLETE PICTURE OF THE
SUSPECT.
AS MORE QUESTIONS EMERGE ABOUT
22-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA.
WHAT SET HIM ON THE PATH TO
ALLEGEDLY SHOOT AND KILL 20
INNOCENT CHILDREN?
ALONG WITH THE BRAVE ADULTS WHO
SO COURAGEOUSLY TRIED TO STOP
HIM FROM THE CARNAGE IN THE
SCHOOL HALLWAY.
AND MORE QUESTIONS ABOUT HIS
MOTHER, NANCY, AT THE HOME THEY
SHARED BEFORE HE SHOT HER IN THE
FACE AND DROVE TO THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
A WOMAN MANY REMEMBER AS KIND
AND LOVING.
>> VERY, VERY KIND, CONSIDERATE,
LOVING, YOUNG LADY.
SHE LIVED HERE... A GOOD PART OF
HER LIFE.
SHE WAS VERY INVOLVED IN THE
COMMUNITY, VERY WELL RESPECTED.
>> ERIC: HER WEAPONS WERE THE
ONES ALLEGEDLY USED BY ADAM.
THEY WERE LICENSED.
PETER DOOCY, LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WITH THE LATEST.
>> Reporter: BREAKING NEWS, WE
HEARD FROM THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT.
HE HE REVEALED THAT BASEED ON
MOST RECENT RECONSTRUCTION, IT
APPEARS THAT THE GUNMAN,
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA DECIDED
TO STOP KILLING TEACHERS AND
STUDENTS AND TAKE HIS OWN LIFE
WHEN IT BECAME CLEAR TO HIM THAT
AUTHORITY WHO IS WERE ALSO
ARMED, WERE CLOSING IN.
LISTEN TO THIS.
>> WE SURMISE THAT IT WAS DURING
THE SECOND CLASSROOM EPISODE
THAT HE HEARD RESPONDERS COMING
AND APPARENTLY, AT THAT, DECIDED
TO TAKE HIS OWN LIFE.
>> Reporter: AUTHORITIES ARE
ALSO SAYING INFORMATION FROM THE
SINGLE SURVIVOR WHO'S RECOVERING
FROM GUNSHOT WOUND THIS IS
MORNING WILL HELP THEM PIECE
TOGETHER EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED
AND WHEN AND WHERE DURING ADAM
LANZA'S RAMPAGE.
WE ARE HEARING A LITTLE BIT OF
THAT OURSELVES NOW, FROM THE
FATHER OF A FIRST GRADER WHO SAW
HIS TEACHER, 27-YEAR-OLD
VICTORIA SOTO GET SHOT.
HE HAS BEEN TELLING HIS
PARENTING MORE ABOUT HIS DARING
ESCAPE, EVERY DAY.
>> THE CHILDREN... ACTED ON
INSTINCT AND WHAT THEY WERE
TAUGHT, WHICH WAS TO RUN.
AND THEY D. THEY JUST RAN... UP
TO THE MAIN ROAD, 100 YARDS
AWAY.
MY SON AND SEVERAL OF HIS OTHER
STUDENTS WERE EXTREMELY BRAVE IN
WHAT THEY DID AND ACTED WITH THE
COURAGE THAT I DON'T KNOW I
HAVE.
>> Reporter: 100 FEET AWAY
FROM WHERE I AM STANDING, THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE OF GIVE
THEIR FIRST NEWS BRIEFING OF THE
DAY.
WE'LL BRING YOU THE LATEST AS WE
HAVE IT.
>> ERIC: HEARTBREAKING STORIES
THAT ARE EAMERICANNING AND
INSPIRATIONAL STORIES ALSO.
WE WILL WAIT FOR THAT NEWS
CONFERENCE, OF COURSE, AS SOON
AS WEHAVE IT.
>> JAMIE: PRESIDENT OBAMA IS
PREPARING FOR A TRIP TO NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, TODAY, CHOOSING TO
PUT POLITICS ASIDE IN THE WAKE
OF THE SANDY HOOK SHOOTING.
STEVE CENTANNI, LIVE IN
WASHINGTON WITH WHAT WE CAN
EXPECT.
>> Reporter: HI, JAMIE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA HEADING TO
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, TO OFFER
COMFORT DO THE FAMILIES AND THE
VICTIMS IN THE VERY TRAGIC
SHOOTING HERE.
REACTING TO THE TRAGEDY, HERE'S
ONE SAMPLE FROM A DEMOCRATIC
SENATOR.
>> THIS CONVERSATION HAS BEEN
DOMINATED IN WASHINGTON BY, YOU
KNOW AND I KNOW, GUN LOBBIES
THAT HAVE AN AGENDA.
WE NEED FOR PEOPLE, ORDINARY
AMERICANS, TO COME TOGETHER AND
SPEAK OUT AND TO SIT DOWN AND
CALMLY REFLECT ON HOW FAR WE GO.
>> Reporter: OTHERS ARE
POINTING OUT THAT SCHOOL
SECURITY IS A BIG PART OF THE
PROBLEM AND A BETTER SYSTEM FOR
IDENTIFYING STUDENTS WITH MENTAL
PROBLEMS WOULD BE VERY IMPORTANT
AS WELL, ESPECIALLY IDENTIFYING
TROUBLED YOUTH BEFORE THEY COULD
POSSIBLY RESORT TO THE VIOLENT
CRIMES AS WE SAW IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
JOE LIEBERMAN IS ADAREICATING A
COMMISSION ON MASS VIOLENCE.
HE ALSO SAID THE ENTERTAINMENT
MEDIA, OFTEN HAVE A DETRIMENTAL
EFFECT ON IMPRESSIONIONABLE
TEENAGERS.
>> THE VIOLENCE IN THE
ENTERTAINMENT CULTURE WITH THE
EXTRAORDINARY REALISM TO
VIDEOGAMES AND MOVIES AND
ET CETERA, DOES CAUSE VULNERABLE
YOUNG MEN, PARTICULARLY, TO BE
MORE VIOLENT.
DIDT DOESN'T MAKE EVERYBODY MORE
VIOLENT.
BUT IT'S A CAUSATIVE FACTOR IN
SOME CASES.
>> Reporter: THE PRESIDENT IS
HEADING TO NEWTOWN.
HE WILL MEET WITH THE FAMILIES
AND GIVE PUBLIC REMARKS AT THE
HIGH POOL AND RETURN TO NEWTOWN,
LATER ON.
>> JAMIE: KEEP US POSTED.
>> ERIC: JAMIE, A TRAGEDY, SO
HORRIFIC AND INCOMPREHENSIBLE AS
THIS SHAKES US TO THE CORE.
AND AT SUCH A DIFFICULT TIME,
MANY OF US FIND COMFORT IN
TURNING TO OUR FAITH.
THIS MORNING, POPE BENEDICT XVI
OFFERED CONDOLENCES AND ASKED
GOD THO TO VICTIMS IN THEIR TIME
OF NEED.
>> I WAS DEEPLY SADDENED BY
FRIDAY'S SENSELESS VIOLENCE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
AND THE FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS,
ESPECIALLY OF THE CHILD HAVE MY
CLOSENESS IN PRAYER.
MAY THE GOD OF CONSOLATION TOUCH
THEIR HEARTS AND EASE THEIR
PAIN.
>> ERIC: JOINING US IS FOX NEWS
CONTRIBUTOR, FATHER JONATHAN
MORRIS.
FATHER, HOW DO WE MAKE SENSE OF
THIS, WITH OUR FAITH, TURNING TO
GOD?
IT'S SO HORRIFIC AND
INCOMPREHENSIBLE.
WHAT DO WE DO?
>> CLOSENESS, AS BOTH MENTIONED
IN PRAYER AND ALSO IN
PERSONALLY, BEING THERE.
IF I WERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, RIGHT NOW I WOULD
NOT BE GIVING AN EXPLANATION.
I WOULD GIVE A HUG.
THE ONE THING THAT THE FAMILIES
TRAGIC SITUATIONS ALWAYS SAY,
WHAT GOT ME THROUGH IT WAS MY
FAITH AND MY FAMILY, THOSE WHO
WERE CLOSE TO ME AND HUGGED ME,
EVEN WHEN THEY DIDN'T KNOW WHAT
TO SAY.
THAT'S THE VERY FIRST BEGINNING.
>> ERIC: YOU ARE GOING ON
CELEBRATE MASS THIS MORNINGS,
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THE
PARISHIONERS AND TO THE VIEWERS
RIGHT NOW TO TRY TO GIFT PEOPLE
WHO HAVE BEEN WATCHING THIS AND
SO EMOTIONAL, SOME COMFORT AND
ASSURANCE OF FAITH -- NO MATTER
WHAT YOUR FAITH IS?
>> MY CONGREGATION'S DISTANT.
I AM GOING TO GET INTO THE BIG
TOPICS OF HOW CAN AN ALL-LOVING,
ALL-POWERFUL GOD LET THIS HAPPEN
AND I AM GOING TO TALK ABOUT
FREE WILL AND ABUSE OF FREE WILL
AND TO DISCOURAGE JUDGMENT.
NO SINGLE FACTOR CAN ATTRIBUTE
SUCH A TERRIBLE ACT.
WE SEE THE MENTAL ILLNESS AND
THE DISTURBANCE WITHIN THE
FAMILY UNIT, OF THE DIVORCE AND
THE NOT TALKING TO THE FAMILY,
ALL OF THIS TAKES -- COMES INTO
PLAY.
THERE IS A FACTOR OF EVIL.
SUPERNATURAL FORCES AND ALLOWING
OURSELVES, OUR SOULS TO GO DARK.
I AM GOING TO ENCOURAGE PEOPLE
TO DOUBLE DOWN ON LOVE.
WHEN WE SEE THIS TRAGEDY, WE SAY
THAT IS CONTRARY TO HUMAN
NATURE, CONTRARY TO HUMAN
REASON.
BUT WE USE OUR FREE WILL AS ONE
OF PARENTS SAID SO BEAUTIFULLY
YESTERDAY, I RECOGNIZE THAT I AM
NOT ANGRY AT THIS YOUNG MAN
BECAUSE HE CHOSE TO USE HIS FREE
WILL TERRIBLY.
BUT I CAN USE IT FOR THE GOOD.
THAT'S WHAT I AM GOING TO DO.
THAT'S WHAT HE SAID.
WE CAN DOUBLE DOWN ON LOVE.
I WOULD LIKE TO MAKE ONE MORE
CHALLENGE.
THIS CROSS EXAMINE, WHEN WE ARE
CELEBRATING SUCH A WONDERFUL
OCCASION AND WE ARE THINKING
ABOUT THOSE WHO CANNOT CELEBRATE
IN THE SAME WAY, MAKE A DECISION
WITHIN YOUR FAMILY TO CHANGE A
TRADITION, TO GET DOWN BEFORE
OPENING THE GIFTS AND IN YOUR
OWN WAY, HOWEVER YOU CAN, TO SAY
A PRAYER, AS A FAMILY, THANK GOD
FOR LIFE, THANK GOD NEAR FAMILY,
THANK GOD FOR RELATIONSHIPS AND
TO DECIDE THAT YOU WILL DOUBLE
DOWN ON LOVE.
I THINK THAT'S WHAT WE ALL CAN
DO WHAT WE WANT TO DO SOMETHING
EVEN WHEN WE ARE NOT THERE.
>> ERIC: THE DOUBLING DOWN ON
LOVE.
THAT'S A MAGNIFICENT MESSAGE.
YOU WERE TALKING ABOUT A FATHER
OF ONE OF THE CHILDREN WHO WAS
KILLED.
OUR HEARTS GO OUT TO ALL THE
VICTIMS.
OPENING PRESENTS, IT'S REALLY
ABOUT THE LOVE OF FAMILY AND IT
IS CONNECTION OF FAMILIES THERE.
THERE'S MR. PARKER THERE, HOW
CAN WE IN OUR OWN LIVES INCREASE
THAT LOVE SO THAT WE CAN MAYBE
HEAL SOME OF THE PROBLEMS THAT
WE ALL FACE IN OUR LIVES AND OUR
FAMILIES?
WE LIVE IN A TIME, WHEN THE
SOCIAL MEDIA CAN SEPARATE US AND
WE FEEL DISTANCE.
WE CAN BE TREMENDOUSLY
CONNECTED.
I FEEL LIKE I HAVE A PARISH THAT
I AM GING GOING DOWN TO IN LOWER
MANHATTAN.
I FEEL LIKE I HAVE A PARISH IN
FACEBOOK, TWITTER.
EVERYBODY'S OFFERING PRAYERS TO
ONE ANOTHER.
THAT'S NO SMALL THING.
WE CAN DOING SOMETHING NOW, WE E
MORE CONNECTED THAN EVER.
THAT'S A GOOD START.
>> ERIC: FATHER, GOD BLESS YOU.
>> I AM TAKING OFF NOT TO GET MY
PARISHIONERS UPSET.
>> JAMIE: THANK YOU FOR YOUR
ENCOURAGEMENT AND YOUR LOVE.
>> THANK, JAMIE.
>> JAMIE: THE FATHER OF ONE OF
THE SHOOTERS' VICTIMS DID
MEMMORRIALIZE.
YOU CAN IMAGINE THE COURAGE OF
EMILIE PARKER'S FATHER, ONE OF
THE SMALL CHILDREN WHO WAS
GUNNED DOWN.
HER FATHER DESCRIBED A KIND
SOUL.
ALWAYS LOOKING TO CHEER UP THOSE
IN NEED.
>> SHE NEVER MISSED AN
OPPORTUNITY TO DRAW A PICTURE OR
MAKE A CARD FOR THOSE AROUND HER
I CAN'T COUNT THE NUMBER OF
TIMES SHE WOULD GO TO SOMEWHERE
WHO WAS SAD OR FRUSTRATED AND
WOULD GO AND DRAW THEM A PICTURE
OR WRITE THEM AN ENCOURAGING
NOTE.
HER LAUGHTER WAS INFECTIOUS.
ALL THOSE WHO HAD THE PLEASURE
TO MEET HER WOULD ALL AGREE THE
WORLD IS A BETTER PLACE BECAUSE
SHE WAS IN IT.
>> JAMIE: AMAZING FROM SUCH A
SMALL CHILD.
ROBBIE PARKER ADDING THAT HE
STRUGGLED TO EXPLAIN HER DEATH
TO HER YOUNGER SIBLINGS, BUT
SAID THE 3 AND 4-YEAR-OLDS SEEM
TO GET THE FACT THAT THEY HAVE
SOMEBODY THAT THEY ARE GOING ON
MISS VERY MUCH.
>> ERIC: WE WILL HAVE CONTINUING
COVERAGE TONIGHT.
THE PRESIDENT WILL VISIT
NEWTOWN.
THERE WILL BE AN INTERFAITH VIG
AND I WILL SERVICE THERE.
HE WILL BE ATTENDING THAT
PROGRAM.
TONIGHT'S COVERAGE WILL BE
ANCHORED BY BRET BAIER.
YOU CAN KEEP UP WITH THE LATEST
DEVELOPMENTS HERE ON THE FOX
NEWSCHANNEL.
>> JAMIE: LI PROMISE I AM GOING
TO DO MY FWOAFT SHIFT GEARS TO
PRESIDENT OBAMA, ALSO GETTING
SET TO NAME MEMBERS OF HIS
NATIONAL SECURITY TEAM DURING
HIS SECOND TERM.
REPORTEDLY AT THE TOP OF THE
SHORT LIST OF SECRETARY OF
STATE, MASSACHUSETTS SENATOR
JOHN KERRY.
FOX NEWS LEARNING THAT THE
PRESIDENT'S EXPECTED TO NOMINATE
HIM ANY DAY NOW, REPLACING
OUTGOING SECRETARY OF STATE
HILLARY CLINTON.
LET'S BRING IN AARON DAVID
MILLER, FORMER ADVISER TO SIX
SECRETARIES OF STATE AND THE
VICE-PRESIDENT OF THE WOODROW
WILSON CENTER.
A PRIVILEGE TO HAVE YOU HERE.
THANKS FOR JOIN JOINING US.
>> PLEASURE, JAMIE.
>> JAMIE: THAT'S AN INCREDIBLE
LIST OF EXPERIENCE.
AS YOU LOOK AT THE CHOICE OF
JOHN KERRY, IF HE IS IN FACT,
SELECTED, WOULD HE BRING TO OUR
NATION'S SAFETY AND SECURITY AND
OUR RELATIONSHIPS WITH OTHER
NATIONS?
>> I MEAN, LOOK, THE KERRY
APPOINTMENT IS SAFE.
IT'S CENTRIST.
HE'S GOING TO BE LOYAL TO THE
PRESIDENT AND HE'S CONFIRMABLE.
BEYOND THAT, I THINK THE CENTRAL
QUESTION IS, HOW MUCH INFLUENCE
WILL HE REALLY HAVE?
BARACK OBAMA IS THE MOST
WITHHOLDING FOREIGN POLICY
PRESIDENT SINCE RICHARD NIXON,
ALL POWER FLOWS IN AND OUT OF
THE WHITE HOUSE ON MOST OF THE
CONS QUENTIAL ISSUES WITH WAR
AND PEACE WITH REGARD TO THE
NATION.
SO I THINK THE QUESTION IS, IF
BARACK OBAMA DECIDES TO
DELEGATE, RATHER THAN DOMINATE,
WHICH HE DID NOT DO TO HIS QUITE
TALENTED CURRENT SECRETARY OF
STATE, THEN I THINK THE
APPOINTMENT OF JOHN KERRY WILL
BE CONS QUENTIAL, TELL MATTER F.
HE DOESN'T, THEN JOHN KERRY WILL
IMPLEMENT THE PRESIDENT'S
FOREIGN POLICY.
THAT'S WHAT THE SECRETARY OF
STATE IS CHARGED TO DO.
BUT USUALLY, WHEN WE HAVE HAD
TRULY CONS QUENTIAL SUCCESSES OF
STATE, HENRY KISSINGER, GEORGE
SCHULZ, JAMES BAKER, THE
SECRETARY HAD A LOT OF LEEWAY TO
CREATE AND SHAPE THE POLICY,
RATHER THAN EXECUTE IT.
THAT'S WAWE DON'T KNOW RIGHT
NOW.
WILL KERRY BE ALLOWED TO DO
THAT?
OR WILL HE ESSENTIALLY BE AN
EXECUTOR OF WHAT THE PRESIDENT
WANTS.
>> JAMIE:
>> JAMIE: WHAT TYPE OF
FOUNDATION DID HILLARY CLINTON,
AS SECRETARY OF STATE LAY FOR
THE NEXT SECRETARY?
>> IT'S REALLY FASCINATING.
SHE WAS A SECRETARY OF STATE WHO
CAME TO THE OFFICE WITH MORE
STAR POWER AND QUALITY THAN ANY
OF OUR PREVIOUS SUCCESSES WITH
THE POSSIBLE EXCEPTION OF COLIN
POWELL.
I MEAN, SHE HAD 8 YEARS IN THE
WHITE HOUSE.
SHE WAS ALMOST THE PRESIDENT --
AT LEAST SHE WAS ALMOST THE
DEMOCRATIC CANDIDATE FOR
PRESIDENT.
SO SHE HAD TREMENDOUS APPEAL.
I THINK BY AND LARGE, SHE
UNDERSTOOD THAT BARACK OBAMA IS
A WITHHOLDING PRESIDENT AND SHE
IDENTIFIED IN ISSUES -- THEY
WEREN'T WHAT I WOULD CALL FIRST
TIER ISSUES.
BUT SHE IDENTIFIED ISSUES-- THE
ENVIRONMENT, GENDER ISSUES,
IMPROVING -- WHICH I THINK WAS A
VERY IMPORTANT ROLE FOR HER TO
PLAY -- IMPROVING AMERICA'S
IMAGE AND CREDIBILITY ABROAD
THROUGH HER RELENTLESS TRAVEL
AND THE FACT THAT SHE WAS VERY
GOOD AT WHAT SHE DOES.
KERRY'S A LOT STIFFER AND MORE
AWKWARD, PUBLICLY.
HE MAY LOSE A LITTLE OF THAT.
BUT DIPLOMACY IS A GET-ALONG
BUSINESS.
LET'S BE CLEAR.
THAT'S ITS STRENGTH AND ITS
WEAKNESS, AT THE SAME TIME.
KERRY IS GOING TO HAVE TO LEARN
HOW TO BE MUCH MORE RELAXED AND
MUCH MORE ACCESSIBLE.
>> JAMIE: AARON, YOU MENTION,
IT'S A GET-ALONG BUSINESS.
ON THE BIGGEST SCALE WE HAVE
SEEN IN I DON'T KNOW HOW LONG --
YOU COULD TELL ME -- THERE ARE
SO MANY COUNTRIES IN TURMOIL, SO
MUCH HATE FOR AMERICA.
HOW CHALLENGING A JOB IS IT FOR
JOHN KERRY OR WHATEVER IS THE
NEXT SECRETARY OF STATE?
DO YOU SEE THEM NEGOTIATING WITH
COUNTRIES LIKE IRAN, WHERE WE
HAVEN'T SEEN THAT HAPPEN?
>> OTHER THAN BEING PRESIDENT,
BEING SECRETARY OF STATE IS THE
BEST JOB, I THINK, IN TERMS OF
SERVING THE REPUBLIC.
BUT AT THIS MOMENT IN OUR
HISTORY, IT'S GOT TO BE ONE OF
THE MOST CHALLENGING.
WE ARE FACING IN THE
MIDDLE-EAST, THE AREA I KNOW
BEST, WE ARE FACING ISSUES THAT
ARE DIVIDED BETWEEN MIGRAINE
HEADACHES ON ONE HAND OR ROOT
CANAL OPERATIONS ON THE OTHER.
IRAN, THE ARAB/ISRAELI CONFLICT,
THE ARAB SPRING THAT LOOKS TO ME
MORE LIKE AN ARAB WINTER IN
GETTING COLDER ALL THE TIME.
THESE ARE ISSUES THAT IMPINGE ON
AMERICA'S NATIONAL SECURITY.
BUT I AM AFRAID THAT OUR
INTERESTS ARE LARGE, BUT OUR
CAPACITY, OUR INFLUENCE ON THE
INTERESTS ARE SMALL.
SO I THINK THE CRITICAL ISSUE
WILL BE WHAT TO DO ABOUT IRAN'S
NUCLEAR WEAPONS PROGRAM.
THAT MAY DOMINATE 2013.
AND I THINK THE PRESIDENT WILL
GO TO FAIRLY EXTREME LENGTHS TO
AVOID A MILITARY STRIKE AGAINST
OOH RAN.
SO AT LEAST FOR 2013, THAT'S
GOING TO PUT JOHN KERRY IN THE
POSITION OF TESTING IN A MORE
SERIOUS WAY, WHETHER THE MULLAHS
IN TEHRAN ARE INTERESTED AT ALL
IN SOME SORT OF NEGOTIATION.
MANAGING RELATIONS WITH RUSSIA
AND CHINA WILL BE CERTAINLY AT
THE TOP OF THE LIST.
AND OF COURSE, THE MOST
IMPORTANT ISSUE OF ALL, HOW TO
KEEP AMERICA SAFE, WHICH IS THE
ORGANIZING PRINCIPLE OF ANY
NATION'S FOREIGN POLICY.
IF YOU CAN'T PROTECT YOUR
HOMELAND, FRANKLY, YOU DON'T
NEED A FOREIGN POLICY.
THAT'S AT THE TOP OF THE LIST.
THE INTERSECTION BETWEEN
POLITIC, NATIONAL SECURITY.
THIS IS GOING TO BE AN
INCREDIBLY CHALLENGING JOB AT A
CRITICAL MOMENT, BOTH IN THE
NATION'S FOREIGN POLICY AND ITS
NATIONAL SECURITY.
>> JAMIE: AARON DAVID MILLER,
WHO HAS ADVISED SIX SECRETARIES
OF STATES.
PLEASE, WE ARE ASKING YOU, AS WE
SEE WHO IS ELECTED FOR THIS
POSITION AND THE NATIONAL
SECURITY TEAM, COME BACK, WEIGH
IN, LET US KNOW HOW THEY ARE
DOING ON THAT.
>> LOVE TO, JAMIE.
TAKE CARE.
>> JAMIE: ALL THE BEST.
>> ERIC: JAMIE, WE ARE AWAITING
A NEWS CONFERENCE ON THE LATEST
ON THE SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT.
THAT'S WHAT IS GOING TO HAPPEN.
IT'S NEWTOWN AND THE PODIUM
BEING SET UP, AS THE CAMERAS AND
THE REPORTERS AND THE NEWS MEDIA
ARE GETTING READY FOR THE LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIAL WHO IS WILL
GIVE US AN UPDATE.
THIS, AS THE NATION GRIEVES,
WITH COMPASSION AND PRAYERS.
WE ARE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE
SELFLESS ACTIONS OF THE BRAVE
STUDENTS AND TEACHERS AND THE
INCREDIBLY TOUCHING STORIES OF
THE LITTLE INNOCENT LIVES LOST.
Sometimes what we suffer from
Is bigger than we think ...
like the flu.
With aches, fever and chills-
the flu's a really big deal.
So why treat it like
it's a little cold?
There's something
that works differently
than over-the-counter
remedies.
Prescription TAMIFLU attacks
the flu virus at its source.
So don't wait. Call your
doctor right away.
TAMIFLU is prescription
medicine for treating the flu
in adults and children
one year and older
whose flu symptoms started
within the last two days.
Before taking TAMIFLU tell your
doctor if you're pregnant,
nursing. have serious
health conditions,
or take other medicines.
If you develop an allergic
reaction, a severe rash,
or signs of unusual behavior,
stop taking TAMIFLU and call
your doctor immediately.
Children and adolescents in
particular may be at an
increased risk
of seizures, confusion
or abnormal behavior.
The most common
side effects are
mild to moderate nausea
and vomiting.
The flu comes on fast,
so ask your
doctor about TAMIFLU.
Prescription for flu.
>> JAMIE: WE'LL BRING YOU OUR
TOP STORY FROM CONNECTICUT.
AND A NEWS CONFERENCE IS
EXPECTED ANY MOMENT.
SO KEEP IT HERE ON FOX.
IN THE MEANTIME, AS WE LOOK AT
THE JOB NUMBERS AND THE MILLIONS
OF AMERICANS WHO ARE STRUGGLING
TO FIND WORK, THERE IS A NEW
SURVEY THAT SHOWS FREELANCERS'
INCOME IS ON THE RISE.
WE HAVE CAREER TIPS FOR THE
SELF-EMPLOY IN THE ERA OF THE
AMERICAN FREELANCER.
THE CEO OF A WEB SITE THAT HELPS
FREELANCERS FIND WORK IS HERE.
THANK YOU FOR BEING HERE.
>> PLEASURE, JAMIE.
>> JAMIE: I WAS VERY THRILLED TO
HEAR THAT THE FREELANCE MARKET
IS OPENING UP.
FOR PEOPLE LOOKING FOR FULL-TIME
WORK, THIS IS REALLY
ENCOURAGING.
WHAT ARE YOU FINDING?
WHAT ARE THE JOBS?
>> WELL, WE ARE SEEING MORE
BUSINESSES REALIZING THAT THEY
CAN FIND AMAZING TALENT WORKING
ONLINE AND MORE INDIVIDUALS ARE
TAKING CONTROL OF THEIR DESTINY,
THEIR CAREERS AND SAYING I AM
GOING TO BE SELF-EMPLOYED AND
USE THE COMPUTER TO CONNECT WITH
BUSINESSES.
WE HAVE SEEN A MILLION JOBS --
AND I MEAN THAT EXACTLY, A
MILLION JOBS POSTED THIS YEAR
WITH INCOME UP OVER 53% FROM
PEOPLE WORKING IN TECH, IN
MARKETING, CREATIVE,
ADMINISTRATIVE WORK.
>> JAMIE: HOW DO YOU SET
YOURSELF APART FROM OTHER PEOPLE
WILLING TO ACCEPT FREELANCE WORK
AND NAIL THE JOB YOU WANT?
>> IT IS A MIND-SET SHIFT.
WHEN YOU BECOME A FREELANCER,
YOU ARE SELF-EMPLOYED BUSINESS.
HAVE YOU TO THINK OF YOURSELF AS
A BUSINESS OF ONE.
HAVE YOU TO MARKET YOUR SKILLS
TO POTENTIAL CLIENTS.
SO INSTEAD OF LOOKING FOR
FULL-TIME EMPLOYMENT, YOU ARE
LOOKING FOR CLIENTS.
YOU WANT TO DIFFERENTIATE
YOURSELF WITH REALLY GOOD
PROPOSALS, AS TO WHY YOU CAN
HELP THE BUSINESS BE SUCCESSFUL,
WHY YOU WILL PROVIDE EXCELLENT
SERVICE AND BUILD A REALLY GOOD
ONLINE PROFILE.
THE ONLINE PROFILE HAS
PRACTICALLY REPLACED THE RESUME.
IT'S MORE COLORFUL AND CAN HAVE
SAMPLES OF YOUR PRIOR WORK,
IMAGES, WEB PAGES, IF YOU ARE A
WEB DESIGNER OR GRAPHIC DESIGN
IF YOU ARE A GRAPHIC DESIGNER --
>> JAMIE: SURE.
>> SAMPLES OF YOUR WRITING.
THE WHOLE IDEA --
>> JAMIE: I WAS GOING ON SAY,
WE'RE OUT OF TIME.
WE HAVE A LOT OF BREAKING NEWS
TODAY AND A PRESS CONFERENCE
COMING UP.
TELL ME, 2013, YOU SAID THE
INCOMES ARE UP 53% THIS YEAR.
DOES IT LOOK BETTER FOR NEXT
YEAR?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
THE TRENDS ARE -- THIS IS GOING
ONLY ONE DIRECTION, MORE AND
MORE BUSINESSES WILL HIRE ONLINE
FREE BALANCE LANCERS AND IT'S
EMBRACED BY MORE STUDENTS, MORE
PEOPLE WORKING FROM HOME, IT'S A
GREAT ALTERNATIVE TO MAKING
MONEY, ESPECIALLY IF YOU WORK IN
AN AREA WHERE YOU DON
LOT OF FULL-TIME EMPLOYMENT
OPPORTUNITIES.
>> JAMIE: GREAT ELANCE.
THANKS FOR INTRODUCING US TO THE
WEB SITE AND THE CONCEPT OF
FREELANCE.
IF YOU WANT MORE ON HOW TO TAKE
CHARGE ON A NUMBER OF CONSUMER
ISSUES, GO TO foxnews.com,
CLICK ON THE AMERICA'S NEWS
HEADQUARTERS AND WHEN YOU GET
THERE, YOU WILL SEE A LINK TO
THIS PROGRAM, TAKE CHARGE
CONSUMER PROTECTION.
>> ERIC: JAMIE, THE PAIN AND
SADNESS FELT BY THE FAMILIES OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, MAY SEEM
CRUSHING AND BEYOND
COMPREHENSION.
BUT IT'S HITTING CLOSE TO HOME
FOR THE FAMILY OF CHRISTINA
TAILER.
SHE WAS THE NINE-YEAR-OLD GIRL
WHO WAS ONE OF SIX PEOPLE GUNNED
DOWN IN ARIZONA IN THE SHOOTING
THAT WOUNDED CONGRESSWOMAN
GABRIELLE GIFFORDS NEXT YEAR.
UP NEXT, HER FATHER.
For those with visions of doing
this...
...this...
...and this,
dancing in their heads...
...we have these.
Home Depot gift cards.
Give the gift of doing,
in-store or online.
>> ERIC: NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
HAS COME TOGETHER AFTER THE
UNTHINKABLE TRAGEDY, GATHERING
FOR A PRAYER VIG TOIL REMEMBER
THOSE KILL IN THE HORRIFIC
SHOOTING AND TO SUPPORT THE
GRIEVING FAMILIES LEFT BEHIND.
WE GO LIVE IT NEWTOWN FOR THE
LATEST.
GOOD MORNING, ANNA?
>> Reporter: GOODS MORNING TO
EVERYBODY AT HOME.
WELL, THE NATION IS SEARCHING
FOR A SAVING GRACE AT PACKED
SUNDAY MORNING SERVICES LIKE THE
ONE BEHIND ME, FEELING HOPELESS
AND DEFLATED AS WE LEARN MORE
ABOUT THE VICTIM WHO DIED IN
FRIDAY MORNING'S MASS SHOOTING.
WE ARE LEARNING MORE FROM THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER.
THE IDENTITIES HAVE BEEN
RELEASED OF THE 12 GIRL, 8 BOYS
AND 6 ADULTS WHO WERE SHOT AND
KILLED.
IN THE HALLWAY OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST FOUND
WITH THE PRINCIPAL WHO WAS
KILLED WHILE CHARGING THE GUNMAN
IN AN ATTEMPT TO END HIS
SHOOTING RAMPAGE.
>> SHE WAS A PERSONAL FRIEND, A
WONDERFUL LEADER AND IT'S A HUGE
LOSS FOR THE KIDS AND THE
COMMUNITY AND HER FAMILY.
>> Reporter: SOME FOLKS IN THE
AREA TOOK DOWN HOLIDAY
DECORATIONS, FEELING GUILTY
ABOUT CELEBRATING DURING THIS
TIME OF TRAGEDY.
OTHERS ARE FINDING A NEW
MEANING, WITH ANGELS TOPPED ON
TOP OF CHRISTMAS TREES.
IT PAYS TRIBUTE TO THE STUDENTSS
AND STAFF MEMBERS SHE LOST AND
LOVED SO MUCH.
>> WE WILL GET THROUGH THIS.
I HAVE LOST FRIENDS.
VILOST STUDENTS THAT VIWORKED
WITH.
>> Reporter: SOME OF THE
PARENT WHO IS LOST THEIR OWN
CHILDREN, MOURNING WITH THEIR
FELLOW NEIGHBOR THIS IS MORNING,
IN PACKED SERVICES.
PARENTS TAKING A BREAK FROM
PLANNING FUNERALS FOR THEIR
LITTLE ONES.
MANY RESIDENTS FEEL THEY HAVE NO
WAY TO HELP THE VICTIMS'
FAMILIES, EXCEPT THROUGH FAITH
AND PRAYER.
AND PRESIDENT BARACK OBAMA, AS
YOU KNOW, IS SCHEDULED TO COME
TO SANDY HOOK TODAY.
THIS IS THE FOURTH TIME HE HAS
COME TO A TOWN IN MOURNING,
FOLLOWING A MASS SHOOTING.
>> ERIC: WE WILL HAVE COVERAGE
OF THAT PRAYER SERVICE LATER ON
TONIGHT, WE ARE WAITING FOR THAT
NEWS CONFERENCE FROM OFFICIALS
FOR THE LATEST.
>> JAMIE: THE HORROR OF THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING IN NEW TABTOWN
IS BEING FELT ACUTELY BY THE
PARENTS OF NINE-YEAR-OLD
CHRISTINA GREEN, WHO WAS AMONG
SIX KILLED IN THE TUCSON
SHOOTING SPREE THAT SEVERELY
WOUNDED CONGRESSWOMAN GABRIELLE
GIFFORDS.
HER PARENTS ARE CALLING FOR
TOUGHER SCREENINGS TO KEEP GUNS
OUT OF PEOPLE IN THE WRONG
HANDS.
AND JOHN GREEN IS HERE NOW,
CHRISTINA'S FATHER.
OUR HEARTS CONTINUE TO GO OUT TO
YOU AND YOUR FAMILY.
THE HOLIDAYS MUST BE REALLY
TOUGH?
>> HOLIDAYS ARE VERY DIFFICULT.
OBVIOUSLY... OUR HEARTS,
THOUGHTS AND PRAYERS GO OUT TO
ALL OF THOSE CHILDREN AND THE
FAMILIES THAT WERE -- THAT WERE
AFFECTED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> JAMIE: YOU KNOW, JOHN, THE
THING THAT STRUCKNY YESTERDAY
AMONG SO MANY OTHER THINGS, IT
WAS DIFFICULT NOT TO HAVE THE
TEARS WELL UP CONSTANTLY, IS THE
TASK THAT A PARENT HAS TO DO IN
ORDER TO CONFIRM -- YES, THAT
WAS MY CHILD.
DR. MICHAEL BODDEN SAYS, YOU
KNOW, THE KIDS WERE SUPPOSED TO
IDENTIFY OUR PARENTS, NOT THE
OTHER WAY AROUND.
HOW DO YOU SURVIVE THAT?
>> THAT'S GOING TO BE VERY
TRAUMATIC.
I DON'T KNOW THE PARTICULARS IN
WHICH THE FAMILIES WERE ABLE TO
IDENTIFY THEIR CHILDREN UP IN
NEWTOWN --
>> JAMIE: THEY USED PHOTOGRAPHS.
THEY DID IT VERY CONSIDERATELY.
>> THAT SEEMS TO BE THE RIGHT
WAY.
I WISH THE PARENTS DIDN'T HAVE
TO WAIT SO LONG.
THAT HAD TO BE I FELT GRUELING,
IT WONDER IF YOUR CHILD WAS
GOING TO COME OUT OF THAT ROOM.
>> JAMIE: I CAN'T IMAGINE THE
THOUGHTS IN A TIME LIKE THIS.
WHAT IS IT THAT PEOPLE DID FOR
YOU AND FIRST OF ALL, LET ME
SAY, EVERYTHING THAT WE LEARNED
ABOUT CHRISTINA WAS AMAZING.
IN HER SHORT LIFE, SHE MADE SUCH
A DIFFERENCE FOR SO MANY PEOPLE,
NOT ONLY IN YOUR FAMILY, BUT
OTHERS.
SHE WENT THAT DITO MEET THE
CONGRESSWOMAN BECAUSE SHE WANTED
TO DO THINGS FOR THIS COUNTRY,
EVEN AT HER YOUNG AGE, SHE WAS
RUNNING FOR STUDENT GOVERNMENT
AND IT WAS AN IMPORTANT EVENT
FOR HER TO ATTEND.
WHAT IS IT THAT PEOPLE DID FOR
YOU IN YOUR COMMUNITY THAT WE
CAN DO IN NEWTOWN AND EVEN HERE
IN NEW YORK AND AROUND THE
NATION FOR THESE FAMILIES THAT
YOU FOUND HELPFUL?
>> THAT'S A VERY GOOD QUESTION.
I THINK SOMETHING THAT WE MAY
HAVE TO OFFER.
AGAIN, I AM SURE THERE IS -- ON
AN INDIVIDUAL BASIS, PEOPLE HAVE
DIFFERENT NEEDS.
BUT TO TELL THE FAMILIES AND
THEIR TOWN TO EMBRACE -- EMBRACE
PEOPLE SURROUNDING THEM.
YOU KNOW, AT FIRST, WE WERE
GOING TO -- ON THE WAY HOME FROM
THE HOSPITAL, AFTER WE HAD
LEARNED CHRISTINA... WE JUST
WANTED TO CRAWL INSIDE OUR HOUSE
AND STAY THERE ALONE FOREVER.
YOU KNOW?
THAT WAS THE -- IMMEDIATE
FEELING AND OUR INSTINCTS.
BUT THANK GOD OUR FRIENDS, OUR
FAMILY, OUR COMMUNITY, EVEN OUR
CHURCH -- THEY DIDN'T LISTEN TO
US.
WE DIDN'T REALIZE THE SCOPE OF
EVERYTHING AT THAT POINT, THE
MEDIA ATTENTION, YOU KNOW, WHAT
WAS GOING TO HAPPEN.
BUT WE ALLOWED OTHERS TO COME IN
AND HELP US.
USUALLY, WE ARE VERY
INDEPENDENT.
WE CAN DO THIS ON OUR OWN.
BUT IT WAS SO OVERWHELMING, WE
ALLOWED OTHERS TO COME IN AND
HELP US WHERE WE NORMALLY WOULD
NOT.
THAT WAS -- THAT WAS THE BEST
MEDICINE, TO ALLOW, YOU KNOW,
YOUR CHURCH MEMBERS, YOUR FAMILY
AND FRIENDS THAT ARE CLOSE TO
YOU AND IN THIS SITUATION, YOUR
FAMILY AND FRIENDS FROM ALL OVER
THE COUNTRY.
>> JAMIE: EVEN STRANGERS.
>> YEAH.
>> JAMIE: WE HAVE NEVER STOPPED
THINKING ABOUT YOU.
THANK YOU FOR ENCOURAGING US TO
DO THE SAME FOR THESE FAMILIES.
WE CAN'T FORGET THE TRAGEDY.
WE NEED TO BE THERE FOR THEM AS
WE ARE FOR AND YOU FOR THE LONG
HAUL.
WE PRAY FOR YOU AND YOUR ENTIRE
FAMILY.
THANK YOU FOR SHARING A PART OF
YOUR DAY WITH US.
>> THANK YOU, JAMIE.
>> JAMIE: WE WILL ALWAYS
REMEMBER CHRISTINE AMOUNT OF ALL
RIGHT.
GOD BLESS YOU AND GOD BLESS THE
FAMILIES OF THOSE IN SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
>> JAMIE: GOD BLESS YOU, TOO.
THANK YOU.
>> BYE-BYE.
>> ERIC: A WONDERFUL, COURAGEOUS
FAMILY.
TO OTHER NEWS, NORTH KOREA,
DEFIED THE WORLD THIS PAST WEEK,
RAISING NEW CONCERNS OVER ITS
NUCLEAR PROGRAM.
YOU MAY RECALL THEY SUCCESSFULLY
LAUNCHED A LONG-RANGE ROCKET,
CARRYING A SATELLITE INTO ORBIT.
THE UNITED STATES CONDEMNED THE
MOVE.
CAN ANYTHING BE DONE TO STOP
THEIR CONTINUING NUCLEAR AND
DOMESTIC WEAPONS PROGRAM.
THANKS FOR BEING WITH US THIS
SUNDAY MORNING.
>> GOOD TO BE WITH YOU.
>> ERIC: WHEN IT COMES TO NORTH
KOREA, A LOT OF PEOPLE THINK
THEY ARE NUTS.
THEY DON'T CARE ABOUT THEIR
NEIGHBORS OR THE INTERNATIONAL
COMMUNITY.
THEY DON'T CARE ABOUT THE
SECURITY COUNCIL.
THEY ARE HOSTILE, BELLIGGERRANT
AND A DANGER.
CHINA IS THEIR PROTECTOR.
WHAT CAN WE DO?
>> ONE OF THE THINGS WE HAVE
DONE IN THE PAST WHICH WAS
HIGHLY SUCCESSFUL WAS BASICALLY
TO BLACK LIST THE BANKS THAT
WERE DOING BUSINESS WITH NORTH
KOREA.
REMEMBER, THEY HAVE TO GET HARD
CURRENCY.
THEY DON'T PRODUCE ANYTHING.
SO WHEN WE FOUND THEY WERE
COUNTERFEITING HUNDRED-DOLLAR
BILLS, WE BEGAN A PROCESS OF
FREEZING THOSE ACCOUNT, NOT
ALLOWING THE BANKS TO DO
BUSINESS WITH THE WEST.
OF COURSE, THE BANKS SAID ALL
RIGHT N. THAT CASE, WE WILL NOT
RUN MONEY THROUGH THIS ACCOUNT
FOR NORTH KOREA.
WE WILL FREEZE IT.
AS A RESULT, KIM JUNG IL WAS
WANT ABLE TO RUP HIS PROGRAM.
BUT WE SHOULD RE-DEPLOY THE
SANCTIONS?
>> WHO LOOKED AT THAT -- WHY DID
THEY LIFT IT?
IT WAS AN ATTEMPT TO GIVE THEM
CARROT, HOPING IT WILL --
>> EXACTLY.
RIGHT.
FOR THE LAST 18 YEARS, AS YOU
KNOW, THERE HAS BEEN AN EFFORT
OFF AND ON TO GIVE CARROTS.
WE HAVE TRANSFERRED BILLIONS IN
FOOD AID.
SOUTH KOREA HAS TRANSFERRED A
LET OF AID.
SO AS A CONSEQUENCE, ACCORDING
TO DEFECTORS, WHAT WE HAVE
REALLY DONE IS TO HELP FUND
THEIR NUCLEAR PROGRAM THROUGH
THIS PROCESS.
THOSE DEFECTORS, SENIOR
DEFECTORS ARE TELLING US, WE
SHOULD SHUT DOWN THE EFFORT TO
TRANSFER AND INSTEAD FOCUS ON
WHAT WE CAN DO TO INTERDICT THE
SHIPS THAT LEAVE NORTH KOREA
WITH WEAPONS WHICH OCCASIONALLY,
WE DO DO, AS YOU KNOW.
BUT WE SHOULD STEP THAT UP.
PUT THE SANCTIONS BACK ON THE
BANK ACCOUNTS AND START
BROADCASTING WITH A TOUGHER
MESSAGE INTO NORTH KOREA TO
REACH THE NORTH KOREAN PEOPLE AS
WE DID IN THE EAST BLOC YOU?
>> ARE SAYING THE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION LIFTED THIS AND
THE RESULT IS WE GET ANOTHER
ROCKET?
>> IT WAS LIFTED ACTUALLY, UNDER
THE BUSH ADMINISTRATION--
>>> OKAY.
>> WE HAVE HAD PROBLEMS -- THAT
WAS A BLUNDER.
WE HAVE HAD THIS PROBLEM OFF AND
ON, AS I SAY, THROUGH THE LAST
THREE ADMINISTRATIONS.
SO THE TIME HAS REALLY COME AT
THIS POINT FOR A DIFFERENT
APPROACH.
THIS APPROACH HASN'T WORKED--
>>> I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO INTERRUPT YOU.
WHETHER IT'S THE BUSH
ADMINISTRATION, THE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION, THE CLINTON
ADMINISTRATION HAD THAT DEAL THE
FOOD AND FUEL DEAL.
THAT DIDN'T DETER THEM.
SO BOTTOM LINE --
>> NOT ONLY--
>>> GO AHEAD.
>>  IT ACTUALLY EMPOWERED THEM
BECAUSE DURING THAT TIME, THEY
WERE SELLING THE ABILITY TO
SYRIA TO MAKE A NUCLEAR DEVICE
IN 2007.
THAT WAS TAKEN OUT BY THE
ISRAELI AIR FORCE THAT TOOK OUT
THAT FACILITY.
BUT THE NORTH KOREAN SCIENTISTS
WERE BUILDING A NUCLEAR BOMB FOR
THE SYRIANS AT THIS TIME.
THIS LAUNCH WAS AN ADVERTISING
PLOY HERE TO SHOW THAT THEY CAN
DELIVER A THREE-STAGE ICBM,
WHICH POTENTIALLY COULD HIT THE
UNITED STATES.
THAT'S WHY WE NEED TO -- TO ACT
NOW.
THERE ARE REPORTS IN THE SOUTH
KOREAN MEDIA THAT IRANIAN
SCIENTISTS WERE ON HAND FOR THIS
LAUNCH.
SO CLEARLY, SINCE THEY'RE
TRANSFERRING THIS TECHNOLOGY,
SELLING TECHNOLOGY, YOU KNOW, TO
IRAN, TO PAKISTAN, TO EGYPT WITH
A SCUD TECHNOLOGY TO NOW TO THE
MUSLIM BROTHERHOOD, NOW IS THE
TIME REALLY FORITOUS WORK IN
CON-- FOR US TO WORK IN CONCERT
TO TRY TO SHUT IT DOWN.
>> ERIC: A MESSAGE TO
POTENTIALLY INCOMING SECRETARY
OF STATE JOHN KERRY TO CHANGE
THE BUSH ADMINISTRATION PROPOSAL
AND PLAN AND GET THE SANCTIONS
BACK ON.
CONGRESSMAN JOYCE, THANK YOU FOR
JOINING US ON OBVIOUSLY, A
DIFFICULT SUNDAY, THANKS YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> JAMIE: BACK TO OUR TOP STORY.
WE ARE AWAITING A NEWS
CONFERENCE ON THE CONNECTICUT
SHOOTING, A LIVE LOOK FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS ARE
GETTING READY TO SET.
TODAY, TWO AUTOPSIES WERE
PERFORMED POST MORTEM ON THE
SUSPECT AND HIS MOTHER.
AN ENTIRE NATION IS GRIEVING FOR
THE LIVES THAT WERE LOST IN THIS
AWFUL TRAPPING DEE.
A DEVELOPING STORY AS THE
INVESTIGATION CONTINUES.
STAY WITH US.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus Liquid Gels
SPEEDS RELIEF
TO YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A DECONGESTANT
FOR YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
THANKS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
>> A FOX NEWS ALERT.
WE ARE AWAITING A NEWS
CONFERENCE.
LET'S LISTEN TO THE LATEST.
>> THE CRIME DETECTIVES ARE
STILL AT THE SCOOBS OF THE
SCHOOLS AND THE SECONDARY SCENE.
WE ARE ACTIVELY WORKING THOSE
AREAS.
THERE IS NOTHING NEW TO REPORT
RELATIVE TO THE INVESTIGATION.
SUFFICE IT TO SAY THAT IT IS
MOVING FORWARD.
AS I SAID YESTERDAY, AND I WILL
NOT -- CANNOT DETAIL PIECES OF
THE INVESTIGATION, BUT I CAN
TELL THAT YOU WOE HAVE RECOVERED
EVIDENCE, CONTRARY TO SOME OF
THE NEWS REPORTS THAT ARE OUT
THERE, WE HAVE RECOVER SOMEDAY
EVIDENCE, IT IS BEING ANALYZED
AND PROCESSED, THE WEAPONRY
INVOLVED, WE ARE TRACING ALL THE
WAY BACK TO THE WORK BENCH,
BEING ASSEMBLED.
EVERY BIT OF ANCILLARY
INFORMATION IS BEING EXAMINED
AND LOOK AT WITH OUR FEDERAL
PARTNERS.
IN ADDITION, THE POST MORTEM
INVESTIGATION BY THE OFFICE THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER IS ONGOING,
HOPEFULLY, EARLY THIS AFTERNOON,
WE WILL BE ABLE TO RELEASE
FACTUAL INFORMATION ON THE LAST
TWO DECEASED IN THIS CASE.
THERE IS A PRESIDENTIAL VISIT
SCHEDULED THIS AFTERNOON.
I DON'T HAVE THE DETAILS ON
THAT.
I KNOW THAT IS BEING PUT OUT VIA
WASHINGTON.
WE WILL LEAVE THAT AS IS.
WE ARE IN THE PROCESS OF -- AND
I AM SURE YOU HAVE SEEN -- AS I
EXPLAINED TO YOU, WE HAVE A
MULTIPLE CRIME SCENES.
WE ARE STICKING SPECIFICALLY
WITH THE SCHOOL.
THE SCHOOL CRIME SCENE, THE
BUILDING ITSELF IS STILL BEING
WORKED ON.
REMEMBER, I TOLD YOU WE HAD A
SECONDARY CRIME SCENE, ALL THE
VEHICLES ON THE EXTERIOR OF THE
SCHOOL.
OUR DETECTIVES HAVE EXAMINED AND
SEARCHED EACH AND EVERY ONE EVER
THEM.
WE ARE BEGINNING TO RELEASE
THOSE BACK TO THEIR OWNERS.
SO SLOWLY, BUT SURELY, WE ARE
BEGINNING TO COMPLETE THE
EXTERIOR PART OF THE CRIME
SCENE.
THE GOVERNOR AND LIEUTENANT
GOVERNOR ARE ON SITE.
THEY HAVE BEEN ACTIVELY INVOLVED
TODAY.
ONE THING THAT IS BECOMING
SOMEWHAT OF A CONCERN AND THAT
IS MISINFORMATION IS BEING
POSTED ON SOCIAL MEDIA SITES.
THERE HAS BEEN MISINFORMATION
COMING FROM PEOPLE POSING AS THE
SHOOTENER THIS CASE, POSING --
USING OTHER I.D.s, MIMICKING
THIS CRIME AND CRIME SCENE AND
CRIMINAL ACTIVITY THAT TOOK
PLACE IN THIS COMMUNITY.
THERE HAS BEEN SOME THINGS AND
SOMEWHAT OF A THREATENING
MANNER.
IT IS IMPORTANT TO NOTE THAT WE
HAVE DISCUSSED WITH FEDERAL
AUTHORITIES THAT THESE -- THESE
ISSUES ARE CRIMES.
THEY WILL BE INVESTIGATED.
STATEWIDE AND FEDERALLY AND
PROSECUTION WILL TAKE PLACE WHEN
PEOPLE PERPETRATING THIS
INFORMATION ARE IDENTIFIED.
AGAIN, ALL INFORMATION RELATIVE
TO THIS CASE IS COMING FROM
THESE MICROPHONES AND ANY
INFORMATION COMING FROM OTHER
SOURCES CANNOT BE CONFIRMED AND
IN MANY CASES HAS BEEN FOUND IS
INACCURATE.
SO I SIMPLY, THAT'S THE NEWEST
TWIST TODAY THAT WE WANT TO MAKE
SURE IS PERFECTLY CLEAR, SOCIAL
MEDIA WEB SITES WITH INFORMATION
RELATIVE TO THIS CASE ARE NOT
POSTED BY THE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE, ARE NOT BEING POSTED BY
THE NEWTOWN POLICE, ARE NOT
BEING POSTED BY ANY AUTHORITIES
IN THIS CASE.
SO ANY OF THAT INFORMATION AND
PEOPLE THAT ARE PUTTING THAT
INFORMATION UP THERE, IN ANY
MANNER, ALL RIGHT?
THAT CAN BE CONSTRUED AS A
VIOLATION OF STATE OR FEDERAL
LAW, WILL BE PROSECUTED, WILL BE
INVESTIGATED AND PROSECUTED.
QUESTIONS.
I CAN TAKE A FEW.
AGAIN, UNDERSTANDING THAT WE
STILL ARE ACTIVE IN THIS CASE,
OKAY.
>> Reporter: A VERY SPECIFIC
TIMELINE OF HOW THE EVENTS
HAPPENED.
I AM WONDERING IF YOU CAN
CONFIRM THAT TIMELINE THAT IS
BEING REPORTED IN GREAT DETAIL
--
>> VERY GOOD QUESTION.
>> Reporter: THANK YOU.
>> THE ONLY ONE SPEAKING ABOUT
THIS CASE, TO EVERY MEMBER OF
THE MEDIA.
I CANNOT RESTATE OR STATE
HEAVILY ENOUGH, I HAVE NOT AND
WILL NOT PUT OUT A TIMELINE IN
THIS CRIMINAL INVESTIGATION AS
IT IS UNDERWAY.
IT IS INAPPROPRIATE.
WE WILL NOT DO THAT.
ANY SOURCES THAT ARE PUTTING OUT
ANY KIND OF INFORMATION LIKE
THAT DOES NOT COME FROM THE
OFFICIAL INVESTIGATING AGENCY,
WHICH IS THE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE, ASSISTED BY THE NEWTOWN
POLICE DEPARTMENT.
WE WILL NOT PUT THAT OUT AS THE
INVESTIGATION IS ONGOING.
I HAVE NOT READ IT.
I CAN TELL YOU THAT.
BUT WE HAVE NOT PUT OUT ANY
TIMELINE INFORMATION.
WE WOULD NOT DO THAT.
>> Reporter: I WOULD LIKE TO
FOLLOW UP ON THAT, YOU HAVE SAID
THERE WERE TWO PLACES INSIDE THE
SCHOOL.
CAN YOU CONFIRM THAT THE
PRINCIPAL AND THE PSYCHOLOGIST
WERE SHOT NEAR THE FRONT DOOR
AND THE CHILDREN AND THE OTHER
WORKERS WERE IN THE CLASSROOMS?
>> WHAT I STATED, RELATIVE TO
THE INTERIOR OF THE CRIME SCENE
THAT WAS THE SHOOTING TOOK PLACE
IN A SINGULAR SECTION OF THE
SCHOOL THAT INVOLVED TWO
CLASSROOMS AND A HALLWAY.
THAT'S AS MUCH AS WE SAID ABOUT
THAT.
WE CANNOT AND WILL NOT DESCRIBE
THE LOCATION OF THE DECEASED IN
THIS INVESTIGATION.
WE WON'T DO THAT.
YES, SIR?
SIR?
>> Reporter: WILL YOU CONFIRM,
YOU SAID YOU ARE INVESTIGATING
THE FIREARMS?
>> YES, SIR.
>> Reporter: THE SHOOTER WAS
TAKEN BY HIS FAMILY MEMBER TO A
SHOOTING RANGE AND --
[INAUDIBLE]?
>> I DON'T KNOW THAT, QUITE
FRANKLY.
AND THAT'S WHAT I AM TRYING TO
GET PEOPLE TO UNDERSTAND IS THAT
WE CAN'T TAKE SEGMENTS OF AN
INVESTIGATION AND DISCUSS IT
PUBLICLY BECAUSE SOMETHING TAKEN
OUT OF CONTEXT COULD BE
MISINTERPRETED.
IT COULD BE MISINTERPRETED AND
NOT FACTUAL, ONCE IT'S
MISINTERPRETED.
THEREFORE, NUMBER 1, I DON'T
KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT THAT, THAT
PARTICULAR STATEMENT THAT YOU
JUST MADE.
NUMBER 2, EVEN IF I DID, I WOULD
SAY, LET US PUT IT INTO THE
CONTEXT OF THE INVESTIGATION SO
WE CAN MANAGE IT AND YOU CAN GET
THE WHOLE, COMPLETE PICTURE OF
WAIS GOING ON.
>> Reporter: DO YOU KNOW
ANYTHING ABOUT THE FIREARMS?
>> JUST THE FOUR FIREARM, WE ARE
WORKING WITH OUR FEDERAL
PARTNERS AND WE ARE ANALYZING,
EXAMINING, WE WILL TRACE THEM
BACK TO THEIR ORIGIN.
WE WILL TRACE EVERY STEP OF THE
WAY AND EVERY TIME THAT WE CAN,
WHERE THEY WERE USED, HOW THEY
WERE USED AND HOW THEY WERE
EXAMINED FORENSICALLY.
A GREAT DEAL OF WORK MUST BE
DONE ON THE WEAPONS.
>> Reporter: ANY OTHER
WEAPONS?
>> I CAN'T ANSWER THAT QUESTION.
I DO NOT KNOW.
OUR DETECTIVES WILL IN FACT BE
ABLE TO ANSWER THAT QUESTION AT
THE CONCLUSION OF THE
INVESTIGATION.
YES, SIR?
>> Reporter: I KNOW YOU CAN'T
GO INTO DETAIL OR MOTIVE, BUT
HOW CAN HAVE DO YOU FEEL THAT
YOU WILL GET A COMPLETE PICTURE
OF THE MOTIVE?
>> I AM CONFIDENT THAT WE WILL
PUT EVERY SINGLE RESOURCE THAT
WE HAVE INTO THIS INVESTIGATION
AND THAT WE WILL VERY EVERY
SINGLE QUESTION THAT IS HUMANLY
POSSIBLE, AT THE CONCLUSION OF
THIS CASE.
WE WILL EXAMINE EVERY PIECE OF
EVIDENCE, SPEAK TO EVERY SINGLE
WITNESS AND CERTAINLY, OUR GOAL,
OUR GOAL IS TO ANSWER EVERY
SINGLE QUESTION.
>> Reporter: DO YOU THINK
NO -- [INAUDIBLE].
>> JUST TO SAY, WE HAVE NOT
STATED WHAT EVIDENCE WE HAVE AND
HAVE NOT COLLECTED.
I WANT TO MAKE THAT PERFECTLY
CLEAR.
HOW CONFIDENT AM I?
WE HAVE THE BEST OF THE BEST
WORKING ON THIS CASE.
WE HAVE OUR MAJOR CRIME
DETECTIVES.
WE HAVE FEDERAL AUTHORITY, WE
HAVE NEWTOWN INVESTIGATORS.
WE HAVE EVERYTHING AND EVERYBODY
FOCUSING ON THIS CASE.
AS EVERYONE KNOW, IT'S A HUGE
CASE.
IT'S A HUGE CASE.
WE'RE USING EVERY SINGLE
RESOURCE AND OUR GOAL IS TO
PAINT A COMPLETE PICTURE SO THAT
WE ALL KNOW AND THE PUBLIC KNOWS
EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
A COUPLE MORE, FOLKS.
[OVERLAPPING DIALOGUE]
>> I AM NOT A SOCIAL MEDIA
EXPERT.
SO I AM NOT GOING TO CLAIM TO
BE.
BUT THERE HAVE BEEN INDICATIONS
OF QUOTES BY PEOPLE WHO ARE
POSING AS THE SHOOTER.
YOU CAN GO ON DIFFERENT FACEBOOK
PAGES AND FIND THIS INFORMATION
OUT.
I KNOW MEMBERS OF THE PRESS
HAVE.
SUFFICE IT TO SAY THAT THE
INFORMATION CAN IN FACT -- HAS
IN FACT BEEN DEEMED AS
THREATENING.
IT'S BEEN INACCURATE.
IT'S BEEN PEOPLE POSING AS OTHER
PEOPLE, AND DISCUSSING WITH
FEDERAL AUTHORITIES, IT'S A
VIOLATION OF STATE AND/OR
FEDERAL LAW AND WARRANTS THAN
INVESTIGATION.
ANYONE WHO IS PERPETRATING THAT
INFORMATION COULD BE SUBJECT TO
ARREST AND PROSECUTED FEDERALLY.
>> Reporter: HAS ANYONE BEEN
IDENTIFYD?
>> THEY'RE WORKING ON THAT RIGHT
NOW.
WE JUST GOT THAT INFORMATION AS
WE WERE COMING TO THE PRESS
CONFERENCE.
A COUPLE MORE QUICK QUESTIONS
AND THEN I HAVE TO GO.
>> Reporter: WHAT DO YOU MEAN
ANY MORE INFORMATION I. THE
MINUTE VITHAT, WE ARE GOING TO
REDUCE IT TO WRITING AND BRING
MORE COPIES AND THE NAMES FROM
YESTERDAY, IF ANYONE NEEDS IT.
BUT THE MINUTE WE HAVE THAT, WE
WILL BRING THAT UP TO YOU.
>> Reporter: DO YOU KNOW WHEN
THE BODIES ARE GOING TO BE
RELLED TO THE FAMILIES?
>> THEY HAVE ALREADY STARTED
THAT PROCESS.
>> Reporter: WHEN DO YOU THINK
THE CHILDREN WILL RETURN TO
CLASSES?
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THE PARENTS
ABOUT SAFETY?
>> A NOTE ABOUT SAFETY IN
SCHOOL, FROM THE EDUCATIONAL
COMMISSIONENER THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT, WORKING WITH THE
GOVERNORS OFFICE, IT IS BEING
EXAMINED ON A LOCAL AND
STATEWIDE BASIS.
THERE ARE MANY PLANS FOR
EMERGENCY PURPOSES IN ALL THE
SCHOOLS IN CONNECTICUT.
ALL OF THEM ARE BEING
RE-EXAMINED AND THE PARENTS
SHOULD IN FACT BE CONFIDENT THAT
LAW ENFORCEMENT IN EVERY
COMMUNITY, STATE POLICE, LOCAL
POLICE, THE EDUCATORS, THE
LEADERS OF THE SCHOOL SYSTEMS
ARE DOING EVERYTHING THEY CAN TO
MAKE SURE THAT THE SCHOOLS IN
CONNECTICUT ARE SAFE.
WHAT I WOULD LIKE THE LIEUTENANT
TO DO IS TO TALK ABOUT THE
SCHOOLS HERE IN NEWTOWN.
ONE SECOND.
>> WE HAVE BEEN WORKING CLOSELY
WITH THE SUPERINTENDENT OF
SCHOOLS HERE.
OBVIOUSLY, WE ARE VERY SENSITIVE
TO THE FAMILIES IN THIS
SITUATION.
WE WANT TO MOVE FORWARD VERY
SLOWLY AND RESPECTFULLY.
THEY DO HAVE SOME TENTATIVE
PLANS, AS FAR AS MOVING FORWARD
WITH SCHOOL.
THE SCHOOL SYSTEM WILL BE
PUTTING THOSE OUT IN THE NEAR
FUTURE.
>> Reporter: DO YOU THINK THE
CHILDREN WILL EVER RETURN TO
CLASS IN THAT BUILDING?
>> AT THIS TIME, IT'S TOO EARLY
TO SAY.
BUT I WOULD FIND IT VERY
DIFFICULT FOR THEM TO DO THAT.
BUT CERTAINLY, THAT'S ONE OF THE
THINGS THAT THEY ARE GOING TO
HAVE HAVE TO LOOK INTO.
>>
>> Reporter: KIDS IN MONROE ARE
STARTING LATER THIS WEEK?
>> THAT'S ONE OF THE PLANS WE'RE
LOOKING INTO.
IT'S TENTATIVE RIGHT NOW.
BUT WE ARE TRYING TO BE AS
RESPECTFUL AS WE CAN.
WE NEED TO KEEP THE KIDS
TOGETHER.
THEY NEED THE SUPPORT OF EACH
OTHER.
A COUPLE MORE QUICK QUESTIONS.
>>
>> Reporter: WITHOUT REVEALING
A SPECIFIC TIME LINE, YOU CAN
SAY ANYTHING ABOUT THE GENERAL
SENSE OF THE SCHOOL?
>> THE MOST GENERAL I CAN BE IS
IT HAS TO BE VERY GENERAL, WAS
THAT THE SCHOOL WAS FORCEFULLY
ENTERED THE FACILITY ITSELF.
OKAY, ENCOUNTERED...
JUST ENCOUNTERED THE STUDENTS
AND THE TRAGEDY OCCURRED.
THAT'S ALL I WANT TO GO INTO.
>> Reporter: [INAUDIBLE].
>> OUR PEOPLE ARE TALKING WITH
EVERYBODY, SLOWLY AND SURELY AND
METHODICALLY.
THIS IS NOT SOMETHING -- THIS IS
SOMETHING WHERE PEOPLE'S HEARTS
ARE BROKEN, AS WE ALL WELL KNOW.
WE HAVE TO BE SENSITIVE.
WE ARE MOVING AS QUICKLY AND AS
EFFICIENTLY AS WE CAN.
THE PEOPLE WE CAN TALK, TO YES,
WE V. WE HAVE SPOKEN TO MANY,
MANY WITNESSES.
BUT THERE ARE MANY MORE
WITNESSES TO PEEK TO, INCLUDING
TO AND NOT LIMITED TO SPEAKING
TO THE YOUNGSTERS.
>> Reporter: WHAT ABOUT THE
WOUNDED?
>> WE HAVE SPOKEN TO THE
WOUNDED.
>> Reporter: YOU CAN DISCUSS
--
>> WE CAN'T DISCUSS WHAT
WITNESSES HAVE PUT FORTH.
THAT WILL BE IN THE FINAL
SUMMARY.
EVERYONE KEEPS ASKING THAT
QUESTION.
I HAVE TO SAY TO YOU THAT FOR US
TO BE ABLE TO GIVE YOU A SUMMARY
OF THE MOTIVE, WE HAVE TO
COMPLETE THE INVESTIGATION.
WE HAVE TO HAVE THE WHOLE
PICTURE BEFORE WE CAN SAY AND
HOW WHY THIS OCCURRED.
THAT'S NOT GOING TO COME VERY
QUICKLY.
>> Reporter: ANY WRITINGS, ANY
NOTES BEHIND?
>> I CANNOT DETAIL EVIDENCE.
WE DON'T DO THAT.
IT'S SIMPLY STATED, WE HAVE A
GREAT DEAL OF EVIDENCE THAT
WE'RE ANALYZING.
THAT'S ALL I CAN SEESAY.
>> Reporter: WITHOUT