>> THANK YOU FOR WATCHING THIS
SATURDAY EDITION OF "FOX &
FRIENDS FIRST."
STUDENT ALL THROUGH THE DAY
FOR OUR COVERAGE OF THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY.
IT CONTINUES IN CONNECTICUT
NOW WITH "FOX & FRIENDS."
♪
>> THE SHOOTING APPEARS TO
HAVE STOPPED.
THE SCHOOL IS IN LOCKDOWN.
YOU ARE REQUESTED TO STAY.
I WILL NEED TWO AMBULANCES AT
THIS TIME.
BE ADVISED, MULTIPLE WEAPONS
INCLUDING LONG RIFLES AND
SHOTGUNS.
>> WHAT IS THE NUMBER OF
AMBULANCES YOU WILL REQUIRE?
>> THEY'RE NOT GIVING US A
NUMBER.
>> SANDY HOOK AND LADDER,
MEDICAL EMERGENCY.
>> GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE.
WE APPRECIATE YOU JOINING US
ON THIS VERY SAD MORNING.
IT'S GREAT TO HAVE STEVE AND
BRIAN HERE WITH ME.
IT'S A TERRIBLE MORNING BUT WE
DO HAVE MORE INFORMATION TO
IMPART TO YOU AND SOME PEOPLE
WANT TO KNOW HOW THIS COULD
HAPPEN IN NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT
AND HOW 20 LITTLE INNOCENT
KIDS COULD BE MURDERED.
WE HAVE MORE INFORMATION ABOUT
THE SHOOTER AND FAMILY
MYSTERY.
>> WE DO.
BEFORE WE GET STARTED LET'S
LOOK AT THE COVERAGE OF THE
TABLOIDS HERE IN NEW YORK
CITY.
AMERICA WEEPS.
THERE IS THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES.
HE SHED A COUPLE OF TEARS IN
THE BRIEFING ROOM YESTERDAY.
SLAUGHTER OF THE INNOCENCE.
AND A PICTURE YOU SAW A LOT OF
YESTERDAY FROM THE BEUP IN
NEWTOWN YESTERDAY WHERE A
POLICE OFFICER LEADS THOSE
CHILDREN SINGLE FILE OUT OF
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
>> SO MANY HORRIFIC ELEMENTS
TO THIS STORY BUT I THINK THE
WORST FOR ME IS THE FACT THAT
THERE ARE 20 KIDS DEAD BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD
AND AS WE LEARN MORE ABOUT THE
SHOOTER, IT SEEMS AS THOUGH
THERE WERE CLUES HE WAS
CAPABLE OF DOING THIS.
>> THERE WILL BE AN UPDATE AT
8:00 THIS MORNING WITH THE
AUTHORITIES.
>> ALL RIGHT.
PETER DOOCY MEANWHILE IS LIVE
IN SANDY HOOK FOR US WITH THE
VERY LATEST DETAILS.
GOOD MORNING, PETER.
TELL US WHAT YOU HAVE LEARNED
OVERNIGHT.
>> ALISYN, WE LEARNED THAT THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER'S OFFICE HAS
BEEN WORKING ALL NIGHT LONG
INSIDE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
THEY ARE TRYING TO HAVE THE 20
CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS WHO
WERE MURDERED INSIDE YESTERDAY
DURING SCHOOL IDENTIFIED BY
TODAY.
NOW, THE KILLER WHO CARRIED
OUT THIS SICK CRIME.
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA
MURDERED HIS MOTHER BEFORE HE
SHOWED UP HERE.
MOST OF THE DECEASED WERE
FOUND INSIDE JUST TWO
CLASSROOMS AT A SCHOOL THAT
MOST PARENTS THOUGHT WAS
SECURE.
>> SANDY HOOK SCHOOL, CALLER
IS INDICATING SHE THINKS THERE
IS SOMEONE SHOOTING IN THE
BUILDING.
WE KNOW THAT THREE OF THE GUNS
USED YESTERDAY WERE LEGALLY
PURCHASED BY ADAM LANZA'S
MOTHER WHO DID BECOME HIS
FIRST VICTIM.
ADAM LANZA'S FATHER AND
BROTHER WERE QUESTIONED AND
CLEARED YESTERDAY BUT NOT
CLEAR STILL IS A MOTIVE AND
NOT EASY IS TRYING TO DEAL
WITH WHAT HAPPENED IN THIS
QUIET CONNECTICUT TOWN.
>> ARE YOU TRYING TO FIND YOUR
CHILD, MA'AM?
>> NO MY GIRLFRIEND DAUGHTER
MY BABYSITTER.
HER AND MY LITTLE DAUGHTER ARE
LIKE BEST FRIENDS AND THEY
JUST TOLD US TO GO -- IF YOU
CAN'T FIND YOUR CHILDREN, THEY
ARE DEAD IN THE BUILDING.
>> AND GOVERNOR DAN MALOY SAID
EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY
YESTERDAY AND FROM EVERYTHING
THAT WE HAVE HEARD AND SEEN HE
WAS RIGHT.
BACK TO YOU IN NEW YORK.
>> PETER, BEFORE YOU GO, THERE
WAS A REPORT BY ANOTHER MEDIA
OUTLET IN THE 10:00 HOUR LAST
NIGHT THAT APPARENTLY THEY
WERE CALLING THE PARENTS IN TO
IDENTIFY THE BODIES OF THEIR
CHILDREN.
HAVE YOU HEARD THAT?
>> THE REPORTS THAT WE HAVE
HEARD ARE THAT THE PARENTS --
RATHER, THE POLICE SET UP A
MAKESHIFT MORGUE INSIDE THE
SCHOOL AND PHOTOGRAPHED THE
CHILDREN AND THEY WERE SHOWING
THE PARENTS PHOTOGRAPHS OF
THEIR CHILDREN TO IDENTIFY
THEM.
>> THEY WANT TO RECONSTRUCT
WHAT HAPPENED AND IT'S A
PAINSTAKING PROCESS BECAUSE
THEY ARE GOING TO HAVE ONE
SHOT AT IT TO FIND OUT WHAT
TOOK PLACE.
WHO IS THE SUSPECT?
>> HE DID IT.
HE IS THE SHOOTER.
>> HE IS ADAM LANZA.
HE IS 2 O0 YEARS OLD.
WE DO KNOW.
THIS IT SEEMS HE IS THOUGHT TO
BE BY NEIGHBORS, BY FAMILY
MEMBERS.
EITHER MILDLY AUTISTIC OR A
LITTLE BIT SOMEWHAT OFF THEY
SAY.
ACCORDING TO ONE OF HIS FORMER
CLASSMATES AND WHO HAPPENS TO
BE A NEIGHBOR TIMOTHY DALTON
AS HORRIBLE AS THIS WAS, QUOTE
I CAN'T SAY I'M SURPRISED BURN
IN HELL, ADAM.
>> YET, THERE ARE LOTS OF
CONFLICTING REPORTS AS CAN YOU
IMAGINE ABOUT WHO HE IS HIS
BROTHER AT ONE TIME THERE WAS
CONFUSION DURING THE DAY
YESTERDAY AS TO WHETHER IT WAS
ADAM LANZA OR RYAN LANZA AN
I.D. WAS FOUND IN THE SCHOOL
THAT SAID RYAN LANZA PEOPLE
THOUGHT THAT WAS THE SHOOTER
WHEN IN FACT HIS BROTHER WAS
IN HOBOKEN AT WORK.
HIS BROTHER SAID HE WAS
AUTISTIC OR HAD AS BERGER'S
SPECTRUM.
VERY HIGH FUNCTIONING, IN
FACT, HE HAS BEEN DESCRIBED AS
A GENIUS.
HE HAS BEEN DESCRIBED AS AN
HONORS STUDENT.
HE HAS BEEN DESCRIBED AS KIND
OF A TECH GEEK, A COMPUTER
NERD.
>> A GAMER.
>> TECHNOLOGY, HAVING GAME
PARTIES.
A PICTURE OF HIM IS EMERGING.
VERY CONFUSED BECAUSE SOME
PEOPLE DESCRIBE HIM AS REMOTE.
IT'S MAYBE HARD TO GET A
HANDLE ON EXACTLY WHAT HIS
PERSONALITY ISSUE WAS.
>> YOU KNOW WHAT?
AND THERE WAS THE -- YOU KNOW,
THE MISINFORMATION THAT IT WAS
RYAN LANDS BUT ACCORDING TO
THE "NEW YORK TIMES" TODAY
TALKED ABOUT HOW THE BROTHERS
HAD NOT SPOKEN OR SEEN EACH
OTHER IN A COUPLE OF YEARS.
LAST SAW HIS BROTHER IN 2010.
I DON'T KNOW HOW MUCH GOOD
INFORMATION IS HE GOING TO GET
ABOUT THE SHOOTER FROM THE
BROTHER WHO LIVES IN HOBOKEN.
>> DIVORCED OFFICIALLY IN
2009.
SEPARATED IN 2008.
THE PARENTS WHERE THE MOM IS
LIVING IN NEWTOWN AND THE DAD
IS LIVING IN NEW JERSEY.
>> AND OF COURSE HE KILLED HIS
MOTHER BEFORE TAKING HER CAR
AND THEN DRIVING TO THE
SCHOOL.
WE HAVE MORE ON THAT
CHRONOLOGY AS WELL.
>> AND THEN LEAVING WITH HER
GUNS WHICH WERE ALL OBTAINED
LEGALLY.
THEY HAD PERMITS.
>> MOMENTS AGO THE FBI JUST
CLEARED THE SUSPECT'S FAMILY
AS WE JUST MENTIONED INCLUDING
HIS FATHER AND OLDER BROTHER
RYAN WHO WAS INITIALLY
MISTAKEN AS HIS BROTHER ADAM
THE GUNMAN BRIEFLY CUFFED.
ANNA KOOIMAN JOINS US NOW FROM
HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY.
ANNA, WHAT DO WE NO KNOW ABOUT
THE LANZA FAMILY.
>> WE CAN TELL YOU QUITE A BIT
OF INFORMATION, BRIAN, GOOD
MORNING TO YOU AND GOOD
MORNING TO EVERYBODY AT HOME.
WE ARE STANDING IN FRONT OF
THE BUILDING THAT IS
APPARENTLY THE HOME OF THE
SHOOTER'S BROTHER 24-YEAR-OLD
RYAN LANZA, HE LIVED HERE WITH
TWO OTHER PEOPLE.
WE WERE HERE YESTERDAY AND
LAST NIGHT AND WATCHED AS COPS
ROLLED UP THE TAPE THAT HAD
BEEN INCIRCLING THE BUILDING
ABOUT 10:00 LAST NIGHT.
YES IT MAY BE QUIET NOW BUT A
COMPLETELY DIFFERENT SCENE
YESTERDAY.
ALL SORTS OF CONFUSION AND
CHAOS AND SOME OF THAT
STEMMING FROM REPORTS THAT
THERE WAS SOMEONE MURDERED
INSIDE THIS APARTMENT BUILDING
AND IT WAS EVEN POSSIBLY THE
FATHER OF THE BROTHERS PETER
LANZA.
WE DO HAVE A RELIABLE SOURCE
AND THE FBI TELLING US NO,
THAT IS NOT THE CASE AND THAT
THE FATHER WAS QUESTIONED BY
FBI AGENTS LAST NIGHT.
THAT SOURCE ALSO TELLING US
THAT RYAN YESTERDAY AFTERNOON
DID NOT KNOW ABOUT EVERYTHING
COMING HERE, SEEING HIS
APARTMENT INCIRCLED BY POLICE.
HE WAS THEN HANDCUFFED AND
TAKEN AWAY.
THE REASON FOR SOME OF THIS
CONFUSION MAY HAVE STEMMED
BECAUSE THE SHOOTER ADAM LANZA
WAS CARRYING RYAN LANZA'S I.D.
AND, OF COURSE, RESIDENTS HERE
IN HOBOKEN ARE REALLY ON EDGE,
ESPECIALLY YESTERDAY, THINKING
THAT A MASS MURDERER MAY HAVE
BEEN LIVING AMONG THEM.
>> IT WAS OBVIOUSLY SCARY TO
SEE THAT SOMEONE THAT COULD
COMMIT SOME ACT LIKE THIS IS
LIVING AMONGST YOU.
YOU ARE WALKING PROBABLY IN
THE SAME NEIGHBORHOOD.
I DON'T KNOW THE PINNER --
PERSON PERSONALLY.
OBVIOUSLY PROBABLY CROSSED
PATHS FROM TIME TO TIME AND
THAT'S AWFUL.
>> WELL, THE FBI SAYS THAT THE
BROTHER AND THE FATHER HAVE
BEEN CLEARED AND POSSIBLY MAY
BE ON THEIR WAY BACK TO
CONNECTICUT.
THAT'S WHERE PETER LANZA
LIVED.
HE DID GET REMARRIED AND LIVES
WITH HIS WIFE THERE.
THEY IN STANFORD.
ALTHOUGH NOT BEING A SUSPECT,
RYAN'S COMPUTER AND PHONE
RECORDS ARE BEING SEARCHED.
THAT WAS TAKEN OUT OF THE
APARTMENT YESTERDAY.
AND RYAN AS MENTIONED HAS BEEN
COOPERATING WITH POLICE GUYS,
AND HAS MENTIONED THAT HIS
BROTHER ADAM POSSIBLY DID HAVE
A PERSONALITY DISORDER AND
MILD AUTISM.
BACK TO YOU.
>> Shepard: ALL RIGHT, ANNA,
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
NOT TOO LONG AGO THE PRINCIPAL
AT SANDY HOOK SCHOOL SENT OUT
A LETTER TO THE PARENTS OF THE
SCHOOL AND SAID WE'RE
INSTALLING A NEW SECURITY
SYSTEM.
GOING FORWARD WHAT THEY ARE
GOING TO DO IS THEY WOULD HAVE
TO BUZZ A DOORBELL AT THE
FRONT OF THE ONLY OPEN -- THE
ONLY ACCESS POINT IN THE
SCHOOL THE FRONT DOOR.
ALL THE OTHER DOORS ARE GOING
TO BE LOCKED.
ACCORDING TO A REPORT IN THE
"NEW YORK TIMES" THIS MORNING,
APPARENTLY THIS SHOOTER ADAM
LANZA WENT UP TO THE DOOR,
RANG THE BUZZER AND THE
PRINCIPAL REALIZED OH, THAT'S
NANCY LANZA'S SON.
I RECOGNIZE HIM.
I'M GOING TO LET HIM IN.
AND IT WAS JUST A COUPLE
MINUTES LATER THAT SHE
ACTUALLY CONFRONTED HIM IN THE
HALL AND HE SHOT HER DEAD.
>> HERE IS WHY THERE IS A
LITTLE BIT OF PROBLEM WITH
THAT STORY IN THAT SUPPOSEDLY
SHE WAS IN A CONFERENCE WITH
THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST AND
WITH ANOTHER PARENT.
SO AT THAT TIME IS THE
PRINCIPAL REALLY THE ONE WHO
HAS TO IN THE MIDDLE OF A
CONFERENCE MEETING HIT A
BUTTON AND CUE SOMEBODY IN.
AND NANCY WE UNDERSTAND THE
MOM LATEST REPORTS WAS SHE
WASN'T WORKING THERE.
SAW A REPORT IN THE DAILY NEWS
TODAY THAT SHE HAD STOPPED
WORKING IN ORDER TO DEAL WITH
ADAM FULL TIME.
>> THAT WAS JUST A PICTURE OF
THE PRINCIPAL.
I THINK WHAT THEY DO IS THEY
HAVE A SURVEILLANCE CAMERA
WITH A LITTLE TV SCREEN.
>> OFFICE BUZZES THEM IN.
IF THEY LOOK RELATIVELY NORMAL
AND OF COURSE HE WASN'T
WEARING I'M SURE THE SKI MASK
OR WHATEVER IT WAS AT THAT
TIME.
LET'S TALK ABOUT THE STORIES
OF SOME HEROISM AND PROFOUND
CARRYING THAT THE TEACHERS
TOOK OVER INSIDE THE SCHOOL
WHEN THE GUNFIRE BROKE OUT.
THERE IS A STORY OF A FIRST
GRADE TEACHER HER NAME IS
KATELYN ROIG.
HAD 14 KIDS IN HER CLASS.
MORNING MEETING.
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
KIDS YOU SIT AROUND IN THE
MORNING AND TALK ABOUT WHAT
YOUR DAY IS GOING TO BE LIKE.
DURING MORNING MEETING THEY
HEARD GUNSHOTS.
THE TEACHER DIDN'T KNOW WHAT
WAS HAPPENING SHE KNEW
SOMETHING BAD WAS HAPPENING.
SHE BARRICADED HER DOOR WITH
WHATEVER SORT OF ROLLING CART
IS AVAILABLE.
THERE IS A BATHROOM IN THE 3RD
GRADE CLASSROOM.
SHE TOOK HER 14 KIDS INTO THE
BATHROOM AND LOCKED THE
BATHROOM DOOR.
SOME OF THE KIDS HAD TO GET UP
ON THE TOILET AND SHE JUST
TOLD THEM YOU NEED TO BE
EXTREMELY QUIET IN HERE,
SOMETHING BAD IS HAPPENING.
LET'S LISTEN TO HER.
>> I PUT ONE OF MY STUDENTS ON
TOP OF THE TOILET.
I JUST KNEW WE HAD TO GET IN
THERE I WAS TELLING THEM IT'S
GOING TO BE OKAY.
YOU ARE GOING TO BE ALL RIGHT.
I HAD PULLED THE BOOK SHELF
BEFORE I CLOSED THE DOOR IN
FRONT OF IT SO WE WERE
COMPLETELY BARRICADED IN.
I TURNED THE LIGHTS OFF.
>> DID YOU TELL THEM TO BE
QUIET.
>> YEAH.
>> DID YOU WORRY ABOUT THEM.
>> I TOLD THEM TO BE QUIET.
I TOLD THEM WE HAD TO BE
ABSOLUTELY QUIET BECAUSE I WAS
JUST SO AFRAID IF HE DID COME
IN AND HEAR US AND MAYBE JUST
START SHOOTING THE DOOR.
I SAID WE HAVE TO BE
ABSOLUTELY QUIET.
AND WE I SAID THERE IS A BAD
GUY OUT THERE NOW WE NEED TO
WAIT FOR THE GOOD GUY.
[CRYING]
I WANTED US TO BE OKAY.
I'M SO SADDENED THAT THERE ARE
PEOPLE WHO IN THIS SITUATION
ARE NOT OKAY.
AND MY HEART GOES OUT TO
ANYONE WHO KNEW THEM AND WAS
PART OF THEIR LIVES.
I CAN'T IMAGINE.
>> Steve: YOU CAN'T IMAGINE.
THERE ARE ALSO STORIES OF
HEROISM A SCHOOL JANITOR
REALIZED WHAT WAS HAPPENING.
RAN UP AND DOWN THE HALLS
TELLING PEOPLE LOCK YOUR
DOORS.
FROM THE INSIDE.
>> IT'S HARD TO IMAGINE HOW
THIS COULD BE WORSE BUT
APPARENTLY IT COULD BE WORSE
IF THESE TEACHERS HADN'T TAKEN
ACTION.
YOU NEVER KNOW HOW YOU ARE
GOING IT RESPOND IN ONE OF
THESE LIFE ALTERING
SITUATIONS.
>> WITH IT CLASSROOMS, THREE
MINUTES, UNBELIEVABLE THE
AMOUNT OF DAMAGE AND TRAUMA HE
HAS CAUSED.
WE'RE GOING TO BE HERE FOR THE
NEXT FOUR HOURS AND OF COURSE
HAVE CONTINUING COVERAGE
THROUGH THE DAY.
STRAIGHT AHEAD YOUR CHILD
DIDN'T NEED TO BE AT THE SCENE
OF THE SHOOTING TO BE
TRAUMATIZED.
JUST HEARING ABOUT IT CAN BE
TRAUMATIC.
AS A PARENT WHAT DO YOU DO AND
ADVISE?
DR. MARK STEALING HERE LIVE
NEXT.
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with uimited
talk and text.
by HTC for $49.99.
Music is a universal language.
But when I was in an accident...
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
Information on my phone.
Connection to doctors who
get where I'm from.
And tools to estimate what
my care may cost.
So I never missed a beat.
We're more than 78,000
people looking out for
more than 70
million Americans.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.
POLICE SAID COME AND LINE UP
AND CLOSE YOUR EYES AND HOLD
ON TO EACH OTHER.
THEY SAID THERE COULD BE SOME
BAD STUFF.
WE CLOSED OUR EYES AND WE WENT
OUT.
WHEN WE GOT OUT, THEY SAID
OPEN YOUR EYES AND WE FOUND
GLASS AND BLOOD ON THE GROUND.
>> HEART BREAKING.
THAT CHILD REACTING TO THE
TERRIFYING ORDEAL AT HIS
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL YESTERDAY.
20 CHILDREN WERE AMONG THOSE
KILLED IN THIS MASSACRE.
WHAT TYPE OF IMPACT WILL THIS
HAVE ON THE SURVIVORS OF THE
TRAGEDY AND HOW CAN WE HELP
ALL CHILDREN COPE WITH THIS
VIOLENCE AND ADULTS BY THE
WAY.
DR. MARC SIEGEL IS AN
ASSOCIATE PROFESSOR OF
MEDICINE AT NYU'S MEDICAL
CENTER AND AUTHOR OF THE BOOK
FALSE ALARM THE TRUTH WILL THE
EPIDEMIC OF FEAR.
DOCTOR, GREAT TO HAVE YOU.
>> GOOD MORNING, ALISYN.
>> Alisyn: LET'S START WITH
THE KIDS WHO WERE AT THE
SCHOOL.
THIS WILL HAVE A LIFELONG
IMPACT ON THEM.
>> THERE IS NO QUESTION ABOUT
THAT THAT CHILD WE JUST SHOWED
HAD TREMENDOUS COURAGE THE WAY
THAT HE WAS ABLE TO WALK OUT
OF THERE AND DID WHAT HE WAS
TOLD TO DO AND HIS PATIENTS
SHOULD BE SO PROUD OF HIM.
BUT THE PROBLEM IS THAT 77% OF
THE KIDS THAT WERE IN THAT
SCHOOL ARE GOING TO HAVE
POST-TRAUMATIC STRESS DISORDER
AND 35% OF THE KIDS AND JUST
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD, LIVING IN
THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
>> Alisyn: MEANING THOSE
STATISTICS BASED UPON PREVIOUS
TRAGEDIES, GENERALLY YOU CAN
FIGURE OUT HOW MANY WILL HAVE
ACUTE SYMPTOMS AFTER THAT.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
THAT'S THESE STATISTICS PUT
TOGETHER BY THE VETERANS
ADMINISTRATION.
THIS IS WHAT IT MEANS.
IT'S GOING TO INTERFERE WITH
THEIR PLAY.
IT MEANS THEY ARE GOING TO PUT
THE EVENTS TOGETHER BACKWARDS.
IN OTHER WORDS, THEY ARE GOING
TO THINK THAT MAYBE SOMETHING
HAPPENED IN ADVANCE THAT MIGHT
HAVE CAUSED THIS TO HAPPEN.
THIS IS HOW THINGS KID.
AGGRESSIVE AT PLAY, SAD AT
PLAY.
THEY MAY HAVE TROUBLE
SLEEPING.
THEY MAY HAVE TROUBLE WITH
DEPRESSION.
THIS CAN GO ON FOR MONTHS.
LUCKILY, ALISYN, THERAPY WORKS
ON THIS.
BEHAVIORAL THERAPY WORKS WHICH
TARGETS THE TRAUMA AND HELPS
KIDS WORK THROUGH IT.
IT IS EFFECTIVE.
I'M ALSO CONCERNED ABOUT
PEOPLE AROUND THE COUNTRY WHO
ARE WATCHING THIS.
>> Alisyn: LET'S TALK ABOUT
THAT OBVIOUSLY THAT'S THE LET
DIRECT KIND OF TRAUMA BUT IT'S
TRAUMA NONE THE LESS.
I HAVE FRIENDS FROM ALL OVER
THE COUNTRY CALLING KNOWING
THAT WE LIVE IN THIS GENERAL
AREA AND THEY'RE DEVASTATED.
PEOPLE CAN'T PULL THEMSELVES
AWAY FROM THE TV.
THEY CAN'T STOP CRYING.
THERE IS TRAUMA EVERYWHERE
TODAY.
>> I HAVE TWO POINTS ABOUT
THIS ALISYN.
FIRST OF ALL PEOPLE HAVE TO
RETURN TO THEIR REGULAR LIVES.
THEY CAN'T OBSESS EVEN ON OUR
REPORTS.
THEY CAN'T TEACH THEIR KIDS TO
WORRY.
I THINK WE HAVE TO ROLE MODEL
OUR KIDS TO BE COMMON.
TEACH OUR KIDS EMPATHY FOR THE
PEOPLE WHO WERE INVOLVED.
EMPATHY FOR THE VICTIMS.
LET'S CARE ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE PEOPLE THERE AND NOT
TALK ABOUT OUR OWN SCHOOLS,
WHICH STATISTICALLY REMAIN
ENORMOUSLY SAFE.
WE'RE REPORTING TOO MUCH ON
SHOULD RERAMP UP SECURITY IN
SCHOOLS ACROSS THE COUNTRY?
THESE TRAGEDIES ARE VERY RARE.
LET'S TALK ABOUT HOW COURAGE
USES THE SAME CENTERS OF THE
BRAIN THAT FEAR DOES.
LET'S REPLACE OUR FEAR TODAY
WITH COURAGE AND CARING.
>> Alisyn: HOW DO YOU TEACH
YOUR KIDS EMPATHY.
>> YOU SHOW IT YOURSELVES.
IF YOU ARE OUT THERE CARING
FOR THE PEOPLE WHO WERE IN
SCHOOLS RATHER THAN WORRYING
ABOUT YOUR OWN LIFE KIDS PICK
UP ON THAT.
IF THEY SEE YOU AS CALM.
WE HAVE TO ALL BE ROLE MODELS
FOR OUR CHILDREN.
SO TODAY TURN OFF THE
TELEVISION IF YOUR CHILDREN
ARE AROUND.
WE NEVER GIVE THAT
RECOMMENDATION.
IF KIDS ARE AROUND.
PUT THE NEWSPAPERS ASIDE.
PUT THE RADIO OFF.
YOU PUT THE TV OFF AND YOU
JUST TRY TO BE AS
COMPASSIONATE WITH THEM AS
POSSIBLE.
>> ALISYN, ANSWER THEIR
QUESTIONS.
THEY ARE GOING TO ASK YOU
ABOUT THIS TODAY.
ANSWER THEM.
DON'T TRY TO SHY AWAY FROM IT.
BUT, DON'T IMMERSE THEM IN IT
AND DON'T MAKE THEM THINK IT'S
GOING TO HAPPEN TO THEM.
IT'S NOT GOING TO HAPPEN TO
THEM.
>> Alisyn: DR. SEGAL GREAT TO
HAVE YOU HERE.
>> THANK YOU, ALISYN.
>> IS THERE ANYTHING CAN YOU
DO TO PREPARE YOUR CHILD FOR
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
ARE THERE SURVIVAL SKILLS WE
SHOULD BE TEACHING THEM
SOMEHOW AND WHAT AGE?
WE EXPLORE ALL THAT NEXT.
You ever notice that some people
just have a knack
for giving the perfect gift?
They put real thought into it.
And find just...
the right...thing.
How do they do that?
More saving. More doing.
That's the power of The
Home Depot.
Pick up a RIDGID JobMax
multi-tool starter kit and
get a free head attachment.
[ Male Announcer ]
JILL AND HER MOUTH HAVE LIVED
A GREAT LIFE.
BUT SHE HAS SOME DENTAL ISSUES
SHE'S NOT HAPPY ABOUT.
SO I INTRODUCED JILL
TO CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SELECTED FOR PEOPLE OVER 50.
PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE IS A
TOOTHPASTE THAT DEFENDS AGAINST
TENDER, INFLAMED GUMS,
SENSITIVITY AND WEAK ENAMEL.
CONDITIONS PEOPLE OVER 50
EXPERIENCE.
CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SO JILL CAN KEEP LIVING
THE GOOD LIFE.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
SANDY HOOK IT UPDATED
REQUIRING VISITS TO RING A
BELL.
SOMEBODY WOULD RING THEM.
IN STILL THE UNTHINKABLE
HAPPENED YESTERDAY.
WHAT SHOULD SCHOOLS BE DOING
RIGHT NOW TO PREPARE AND
PROTECT THEIR STUDENTS?
A FORMER DETECTIVE FOR THE NEW
YORK CITY POLICE DEPARTMENT
AND HE IS A SECURITY EXPERT AS
WELL.
HARRY, THANKS FOR COMING IN ON
THIS SATURDAY MORNING.
>> GOOD MORNING.
>> Steve: TERRIBLE STORY.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT THE
REACTION PLAN WAS AT THE
SCHOOL WE DO KNOW THEY HAD
RECENTLY IN-STORED A NEW
DOORBELL.
>> A DOORBELL IS NICE BUT IN A
SITUATION LIKE THIS YOU
BASICALLY NEED WHAT'S CALLED
THE EMERGENCY ACTION PLAN.
THIS IS A SPECIAL PLAN THAT
YOU SET UP IN THE EVENT AN
ATTACK LIKE THIS OCCURS.
THIS WAY YOUR PEOPLE KNOW HOW
TO REACT.
YOU KNOW, I SAW A LOT OF
PEOPLE ON TV YESTERDAY,
ESPECIALLY THE TEACHERS, OKAY,
THAT WERE TALKING ABOUT HOW
THEY REACTED MUCH WHEN
SOMETHING HAPPENS.
IT'S JUST LIKE A FIRE DRILL.
YOU KNOW, PUTTING AN EMERGENCY
ACTION PLAN TOGETHER IS KEY
THEY NEED TO KNOW HOW TO REACT
WHEN SOMETHING LIKE THIS
OCCURS.
ALL RIGHT?
SO THE TEACHERS NEED TO BE
TRAINED, ALL RIGHT.
THE REST OF THE SCHOOL STAFF
NEEDS TO BE TRAINED.
>> Steve: SURE.
>> ALL RIGHT.
AND YOU HAVE GOT TO WORK IN
CONJUNCTION WITH THE POLICE
DEPARTMENT ON HOW TO REACT TO
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
>> Steve: IT DOES SOUND LIKE
THEY HAD THE RIGHT IDEA.
THE JANITOR APPARENTLY
SELFLESSLY RAN UP AND DOWN THE
HALLS TELLING THE TEACHERS TO
LOCK THE DOORS FROM THE INSIDE
AND APPARENTLY SOMEBODY KEYED
THE INTERCOM, THE PUBLIC
ADDRESS SYSTEM.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> Steve: FROM THE OFFICE SO
THAT PEOPLE COULD HEAR THE
SCREAMS AND SHOOTING AS WELL
AND PERHAPS THAT ACTUALLY
SAVED SOME LIVES.
>> IT PROBABLY DEFINITELY DID.
THE FIRST TWO MINUTES ARE THE
MOST IMPORTANT TIME IN AN
ACTIVE SHOOTER ATTACK.
THAT'S WHEN MOST OF THE DAMAGE
OCCURRED.
I WAS LISTENING TO SOME OF THE
RADIO TRANSMISSIONS FROM THE
POLICE DEPARTMENT YESTERDAY IT
SEEMS LIKE BY THE TIME THE
POLICE OFFICERS ALREADY
ARRIVED THAT THE SHOOTER HAD
ALREADY KILLED HIMSELF.
IF THAT'S WHAT HAPPENED.
>> Steve: DO YOU THINK SCHOOLS
SHOULD HAVE ARMED GUARDS.
>> YES, WITHOUT A DOUBT.
YOU KNOW, WE HAVE THEM HERE IN
NEW YORK.
IT WOULD PROBABLY TAKE NOTHING
FOR ONE POLICE OFFICER TO BE
AROUND THE SCHOOL AREA BETWEEN
9:00 AND 3:30 IN THE
AFTERNOON.
>> Steve: JUST A LOCAL POLICE
OFFICER.
>> THAT WOULD BE PART OF HIS
DUTY.
>> EXACTLY NOT TO STAND IN
FRONT OF THE SCHOOL.
IDEALLY, YOU WOULD WANT A
SECURITY PERSON WHO WAS IN
PLAIN CLOTHES BECAUSE EVEN IF
YOU HAD SOMEBODY ARMED IN A
UNIFORM, THE ACTIVE SHOOTER
WOULD PROBABLY KNOW WHO HE IS
JUST BY AND THEN JUST SHOOT
HIM FIRST.
>> Steve: HARRY, IT'S A SAD
SITUATION TO THINK THAT WE
WOULD HAVE TO HAVE ARMED
GUARDS AT OUR SCHOOLS.
IN THIS PARTICULAR TOWN I HAVE
BEEN UP IN THAT AREA IT'S
IDEAL LICK, BEAUTIFUL.
LAST PLACE YOU WOULD THINK
SOMETHING LIKE THIS WOULD
HAPPEN.
>> EXACTLY.
WE LIVE IN A DIFFERENT WORLD
TODAY.
YOU KNOW, PEOPLE NEED TO
UNDERSTAND THAT.
YOU KNOW.
>> Steve: THERE ARE JUST EVIL
PEOPLE OUT THERE.
>> YES, THERE ARE.
AND THIS GUY WAS A SOCIOPATH.
EVERYBODY IS TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT WHY THIS GUY WOULD DO
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
ALL RIGHT, THE BOTTOM LINE IS
ONLY A SOCIOPATH COULD
UNDERSTAND WHAT THIS GUY DID.
YOU AND I ARE JUST HEART
BROKEN OVER THIS.
>> INDEED.
HARRY A REAL PLEASURE.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR JOINING U.
SORRY IT HAD TO BE THESE
CIRCUMSTANCES.
SANDY HOOK'S PRINCIPAL HEARD
GUNSHOTS, RAN TOWARD THEM.
HER STORY NEXT.
[ roasting firewood ]
♪
MANY HOT DOGS
ARE WITHIN YOU.
TRY PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO,
IT'S THE POWER OF PEPTO,
BUT IT FITS IN YOUR POCKET.
NOW TELL THE WORLD
DANIEL...
OF PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO.
And also to build my career.
So I'm not about to always let
my frequent bladder urges,
or the worry my pipes
might leak get in the way
of my busy lifestyle.
That's why I take care,
with VESIcare.
Once-daily VESIcare can help
control your bladder muscle
and is proven to treat
overactive bladder
with sympts of
frequent urges and leaks
day and night.
If you have certain stomach or
glaucoma problems,
or trouble emptying
your bladder,
do not take VESIcare.
VESIcare may cause allergic
reactions that may be serious.
If you experience swelling of
the face, lips,
throat or tongue,
stop taking VESIcare
and get emergency help.
Tell your doctor right away if
you have severe abdominal pain,
or become constipated for three
or more days.
VESIcare may
cause blurred vision,
so use caution while driving
or doing unsafe tasks.
Common side effects
are dry mouth, constipation,
and indigestion.
I've worked hard
to get to where I am...
and I've got better
aces to go
than always
going to the bathroom.
So take charge of your symptoms
by talking to your doctor
and go to vesicare.com
for a free trial offer.
AT LEGALZOOM, WE'VE CREATED
A BETTER PLACE
TO HANDLE YOUR LEGAL NEEDS.
MAYBE YOU HAVE QUESTIONS
ABOUT INCORPORATING
A BUSINESS
YOU'D LIKE TO START.
OR QUESTIONS
ABOUT PROTECTING YOUR FAMILY
WITH A WILL OR LIVING TRUST.
AND YOU'D LIKE TO FIND
THE RIGHT ATTORNEY
TO HELP GUIDE YOU ALONG,
ANSWER ANY QUESTIONS
AND OFFER ADVICE.
WITH AN "A" RATING FROM
THE BETTER BUSINESS BUREAU
LEGALZOOM HELPS YOU GET
PERSONALIZED AND AFFORDABLE
LEGAL PROTECTION.
IN MOST STATES, A LEGAL PLAN
ATTORNEY IS AVAILABLE WITH
EVERY PERSONALIZED DOCUMENT
TO ANSWER ANY QUESTIONS.
GET STARTED AT LEGALZOOM.COM
TODAY.
AND NOW YOU'RE PROTECTED.
♪
>> CHURCHES IN NEWTOWN WERE
FILLED LAST NIGHT.
HUNDREDS OF NEWTOWN RESIDENTS
GATHERING FOR A MEMORIAL
SERVICE.
SO MANY PEOPLE.
SOME EVEN HAD TO STAND
OUTSIDE.
IT JUST DOES NOT SEEM LIKE
IT'S EVEN POSSIBLE.
>> THERE IS NO WORDS.
IT'S SHEAR TERROR AND A SENSE
OF IMMOOD I CAN'T TELL URGENCY
AND, YOU KNOW, TO GET TO YOUR
CHILD AND TO BE THERE TO
PROTECT THEM.
>> I GOT AN EMERGENCY PHONE
CALL THAT THERE HAD BEEN A
SHOOTING BUT THEY DIDN'T SAY
WHERE.
AND THAT THE SCHOOLS WERE ON
LOCKDOWN.
I GOT AN TEXT A.P. SHOOTING AT
THE SCHOOL SANDY HOOK.
I THOUGHT OH MY GOD.
I WENT TO THE SCHOOL THERE
WERE SOME HISTORICAL MOMS THAT
I KNEW AND I SAID WHAT'S GOING
ON?
SHE SAID THE PRINCIPAL IS DEAD
AND THAT CHILDREN CAME OUT
WITH BLOOD.
>> WE'RE COPING.
WE'RE STILL TRYING TO FIND
OUT, YOU KNOW, WHAT'S GOING
ON.
IT'S A LITTLE NERVE WRACKING.
AS YOU CAN TELL BEHIND US WE
DO HAVE A FEW MORE CARS
PULLING IN AT THIS TIME.
HOW MANY SHOOTERS?
HOW MANY PEOPLE ARE INJURED?
>> SHE WAS IN A SMALL CLASS, A
READING GROUP AND THEY STARTED
HEARING, I GUESS BANGS AND HER
TEACHER WHICH I'M SO GRATEFUL
FOR THERE WAS JUST A SMALL
GROUP, THEY RUSHED THE KIDS
INTO THE BATHROOM AND THEY
LOCKED THE DOOR AND THEY JUST
TOLD THE CHILDREN THAT IT WAS
HAMMERING AND TRIED TO KEEP
THEM CALM AND THE NEXT THING I
KNOW BECAUSE IT'S VERY HARD TO
GET COMPLETE STORY.
THE NEXT THING I KNOW IS THAT
THE POLICE CAME IN AND THEY
WERE KNOCKING ON THE DOOR TO
BE LET OUT OF THE CLASSROOM
AND WHEN THEY WERE SHE HAD
SEEN GLASS AND BLOOD.
I UNDERSTAND THAT CHILD'S
FACE.
>> LATER ON SHE WAS TALKING
ABOUT HOW, YOU KNOW, WHILE SHE
WAS WALKING DOWN THE HALLWAY,
THE POLICE TOLD THEM TO CLOSE
THEIR EYES BECAUSE, I MEAN
OBVIOUSLY IT WAS A VERY
SENSITIVE SCENE.
AND SHE SAID SHE HEARD
GUNSHOTS AND -- ACTUALLY, WHAT
SHE TOLD ME WAS IN THE
BEGINNING THE INTERCOM CAME ON
AND THAT SHE HEARD A SCREAM ON
THE INTERCOM AROUND THE
SCHOOL.
AND THE INTERCOM WENT
IMMEDIATELY OFF.
AND I'M NOT SURE THE SPECIFICS
OF HOW THE SCHOOL GOT LOCKED
DOWN BUT SHE DID HEAR SCHEMES
ON THE INTERCOM AND GUNSHOTS.NGE
THIS.
IT'S SENSELESS.
IT DOESN'T.
BUT OUR HEARTS ARE WITH
EVERYBODY.
EVERYBODY, EVERY PARENT.
EVERY MOTHER, FATHER,
GRANDFATHER, GRANDMOTHER,
BROTHER, SISTER RIGHT NOW FOR
ALL THE OTHER CHILDREN.
>> EVERYBODY SEEMS TO BE DOING
OKAY.
BUT, YOU KNOW, COUPLE FRIENDS
THAT WE HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE TO
GET IN TOUCH WITH THEM.
YOU KNOW, WE HOPE EVERYTHING
IS OKAY WITH THAT.
>> Steve: WHAT A DAY YESTERDAY
WAS.
AND THAT LAST PICTURE OF THE
LITTLE BOY WALKING OUT IN THE
POLICE OFFICER'S COAT.
IN THAT, YOU HEARD ONE YOUNG
MAN TALK A LITTLE BIT ABOUT
HOW SOMEBODY IN THE OFFICE
APPARENTLY PUSHED DOWN THE
BUTTON FOR THE INTERCOM WE
WERE TALKING TO HARRY HAULK.
IT MAY HAVE BEEN THE
PRINCIPAL.
WHOEVER IT WAS PUSHED IT DOWN
LONG ENOUGH SO THE ENTIRE
SCHOOL HEARD THE COMMOTION AT
THE FRONT OF THE SCHOOL.
EVERYBODY HEARD ON THE
INTERCOM.
THAT MAY HAVE ACTUALLY SAVED
SOME LIVES.
IMMEDIATELY TEACHERS HEARD
THAT THOUGHT SOMETHING WAS
WRONG AND STARTED LOCKING
DOORS.
>> THINK ABOUT THAT, TOO.
IT'S WORTH -- IT'S WORTH THE
DAMAGE DONE BUT THEN YOU GET
TO HEAR THE HORROR AS IT
UNFOLDS ON ALL THE SPEAKERS IN
THE CLASSROOMS.
YOU REACT TO IT BUT YOU STILL
TAKE IT IN.
>> IT ALLOWED THEM TO
BARRICADE THEMSELVES IN THE
ROOM WHICH WAS OBVIOUSLY
HELPFUL.
WE NEED TO TALK ABOUT THE
PRINCIPAL.
A I DON'T MEAN 27 YEARS OLD.
DAWN HOCKSPRUNG I HOPE I'M
SAYING THAT RIGHT.
DESCRIBED AS INCREDIBLY
DEDICATED AND PASSIONATE
EDUCATOR.
SHE HAD A TWITTER STREAM.
SHE WOULD APPARENTLY SEND OUT
MESSAGES ALL THE TIME ABOUT
THE THINGS THAT SHE WAS
EXCITED ABOUT AT SCHOOL, THE
WAY SHE WAS EXCITED TO WELCOME
NEW KINDERGARTNERS THIS YEAR
INTO THE CLASS.
I THINK THE QUOTE WAS I'M SO
EXCITED THAT THEY HAVE A
LIFETIME OF LEARNING AHEAD OF
THEM.
SHE IS -- ONE OF THE THINGS
THAT SHE IS NOTED FOR TODAY IS
THAT SHE INSTALLED THIS NEW
SECURITY SYSTEM.
AND THE WAY IT WORKS.
THE WAY IT WORKS IN MOST
PUBLIC SCHOOLS IS THAT THERE
IS A CAMERA AT THE FRONT DOOR.
THE DOOR IS LOCKED.
YOU HAVE TO BUZZ EVEN AS A
PARENT YOU BUZZ AND THEN
SOMEBODY GIVES LIKE A VISUAL
IDENTIFICATION IN THE ROOM AND
BUZZ -- IN THE OFFICE AND
BUZZES YOU IN.
OF COURSE, WHEN PEOPLE ARE
BUSY, AND YOU ARE NOT
EXPECTING A MASS MURDERER,
PEOPLE PROBABLY, ABSENT
MINDEDLY BUZZ PEOPLE IN ALL
THE TIME.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT THE
SITUATION WAS YESTERDAY.
OBVIOUSLY WE CAN ASSUME THE
GUNMAN WASN'T WEARING COMBAT
CAMO HEAD GEAR WHEN HE BUZZED.
BUT THIS JUST HAPPENS ALL THE
TIME THAT, YOU KNOW, YOU THINK
IT'S A PARENT AND ALSO WE HAD
HEARD THAT THE PRINCIPAL
RECOGNIZED HIM, ADAM LANZA
SOMEHOW BECAUSE PERHAPS HIS
MOTHER WAS CONNECTED TO THE
SCHOOL.
>> "NEW YORK TIMES."
I GIVE SO MUCH CREDIT TO THE
PRINCIPAL WHEN YOU HEAR GUN
SHOTS A LOT OF PEOPLE WOULD
SAY DUCK AND COVER.
SHE AND THE PSYCHIATRIST,
SCHOOL PSYCHIATRIST WHO WAS
GOING TO ACCORDING TO ONE
REPORT RETIRE AT THE END OF
THIS YEAR WALK OUT TOWARDS THE
GUNSHOTS AND THEN SHE WAS
KILLED.
WHAT KIND OF PERSON WAS SHE?
WE MENTIONED ABOUT THE TWEETS.
SHE WOULD BE SOMEBODY THAT
WOULD BE SILLY.
I REMEMBER PRINCIPALS FAR
REMOVED FROM KIDS.
OH MY GOODNESS.
>> SCARY.
>> SHE WOULD DRESS IN SILLY
OUTFITS ON WEDNESDAYS.
WACKY WEDNESDAYS WHERE THEY
ENCOURAGED KIDS TO DRESS IN A
FUNNY, CRAZY WAY.
SO SHE WAS SOMEBODY THAT
PEOPLE COULD REALLY RELATE TO
THAT WAS REALLY PUMPED UP TO
DO HER JOB ON A DAILY BASIS.
A THE LOVE THE KIDS WERE
EVIDENTLY ASKING THEIR MOMS
HOW WAS THE PRINCIPAL.
>> Steve: IT WAS APPARENTLY
HER IDEA TO INSTALL THIS DOOR
BUZZER.
ALI WAS TALKING ABOUT THE
SAFETY DRILL.
HERE IS A TWEET SHE SENT OUT
ON OCTOBER 17TH.
SAFETY FIRST AT SANDY HOOK.
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL DAY FOR OUR
ANNUAL EVACUATION DRILL.
THEY ALSO HAD INCLUDED ON THE
TWEET AN IMAGE OF THAT.
WHEN IT WAS TIME FOR THE
INSTALLATION OF THE NEW
DOORBELL DID SEND OUT A LETTER
TO THE PARENTS AND SAID,
QUOTE:  PLEASE UNDERSTAND THAT
WITH NEARLY 700 STUDENTS AND
OVER 1,000 PARENTS
REPRESENTING 500 FAMILIES MOST
PARENTS WILL BE ASKED TO SHOW
IDENTIFICATION.
THAT IS YOU RING THE DOORBELL
AND THEN YOU MIGHT HAVE TO
SHOW SOME IDENTIFICATION.
BUT AS WE DETAILED THIS
MORNING THERE IS A REPORT FROM
THE "NEW YORK TIMES" TODAY
THAT APPARENTLY SHE RECOGNIZED
THE SHOOTER BECAUSE THAT WAS
NANCY'S SON.
SHE KNEW NANCY.
NANCY WAS A TEACHER THERE.
WE DON'T KNOW FULL TIME, PART
TIME, RETIRED, WHATEVER.
BUT BUZZED HIM IN AND WITHIN
TWO MINUTES THAT KID WITH A
GUN KILLED HER.
>> Brian: MEANWHILE JAMES
ROSEN IS OVER IN WASHINGTON
NOW.
YOU KNOW, THE PRESIDENT SPOKE
YESTERDAY EMOTIONALLY.
HE SAID NOT AS A PRESIDENT.
I SPEAK TO YOU NOW AS A
PRESIDENT.
UNDERSTANDS WHAT HE WAS GOING
THROUGH AND WHAT WE'RE ALL
GOING THROUGH.
LISTEN.
>> THOSE WHO DIED TODAY WERE
CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS
OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
>> Steve: YESTERDAY THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
HAD THE FACE OF THE NATION
RIGHT THERE WIPING AWAY THE
TEAR.
>> WE ARE SEEING THIS MORE AND
MORE.
SEEMS LIKE WE ARE AURORA
SHOOTING AND KICKED WITH WITH
GABRIEL GIFFORDS AND WHAT
HAPPENED IN THAT PARKING LOT
THAT DAY.
MORE AND MORE HEARING ABOUT
THE SAME THEMES.
>> EVIL.
>> Alisyn: SO FOR MORE ON THE
PRESIDENT'S REACTION WE GO TO
JAMES ROSEN IN WASHINGTON.
GOOD MORNING, JAMES.
>> ALISYN AND GUYS, GOOD
MORNING TO YOU.
ACTUALLY WE SAW AN INTERESTING
RANGE OF REACTION FROM
OFFICIAL WASHINGTON, THE
NATION'S TOP ELECTED
REPUBLICAN HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER ISSUED A CALL FOR
UNITY YESTERDAY.
THE HORROR OF THIS DAY SEEMS
SO UNBEARABLE THE OHIO
LAWMAKER SAID WE WILL LOCK
ARMS AND UNITE AS CITIZENS FOR
THAT IS HOW AMERICANS RISE
ABOVE UNSPEAKABLE EVIL.
CONGRESS' LEADING ADVOCATE FOR
GUN CONTROL KAREN MCCARTHY OF
NEW YORK WHOSE HUSBAND WAS
KILLED AND SON BADLY INJURED
MASS SHOOTING ON LONG ISLAND
RAILROAD BACK IN 1993 SHE
STRUCK A MORE ASSERTIVE TONE
TELLING POLITICO I AGREE THIS
IS NOT THE TIME TO TALK ABOUT
GUN CONTROL.
IT SHOULD HAVE BEEN TALKED
ABOUT YEARS AGO WHEN WE
STARTED HAVING THESE MASS
SHOOTINGS.
IT SHOULD HAVE BEEN DONE WHEN
GABRIEL GIFFORDS WAS SHOT.
MCCARTHY DESCRIBED A
CONVERSATION SHE HAD REQUIRE
TO ELECTION DAY WITH WHITE
HOUSE CHIEF OF STAFF JACK LU
IN WHICH SHE VOWED TO REVIVE
THE ISSUE IN THE NEXT ISSUE OF
CONGRESS.
I KNOW THE PRESIDENT IS GOING
THROUGH AN ELECTION I'M
TELLING YOU AFTER AN ELECTION
I'M COMING OUT FULL FORCE.
I WAS JUST GIVING THE WHITE
HOUSE A HEADS UP THAT THE
GLOVES ARE OFF ON MY SIDE AND
I WAS GOING TO DO EVERYTHING I
POSSIBLY COULD IF THAT MEANT
EMBARRASSING EVERYBODY,
MCCARTHY SAID, THAT'S WHAT I
WOULD DO.
IN HIS WEEKLY SATURDAY
ADDRESS, PRESIDENT OBAMA
MOSTLY REPEATED HIS STATEMENT
OF YESTERDAY.
HE KEPT HIS EMOTIONS IN CHECK,
HOWEVER.
HE CORRECTLY PRONOUNCED THE
NAME OF THE TOWN IN
CONNECTICUT AND ADDED ANOTHER
CITY TO THE LITANY OF THEM HE
HAD IN FRIDAY'S REMARKS.
>> AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, A SHOPPING MALL IN
OREGON, A HOUSE OF WORSHIP IN
WISCONSIN, A MOVIE THEATER IN
COLORADO, COUNTLESS STREET
CORNERS AND PLACES LIKE
CHICAGO AND PHILADELPHIA, ANY
OF THESE NEIGHBORHOODS COULD
BE OUR OWN.
SO WE HAVE TO COME TOGETHER
AND WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO
TAKE MEANINGFUL ACTION TO
PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE
THIS FROM HAPPENING.
U REGARDLESS OF POLITICS.
>> WHAT EXACTLY THAT
MEANINGFUL ACTION SHOULD BE,
THE PRESIDENT HAS NOT YET
SPECIFIED.
BACK TO YOU GUYS IN NEW YORK.
>> Shepard: ALL RIGHT, JAMES.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> Brian: MIKE BLOOMBERG ALSO
SOMEBODY GOING AFTER THE
PRESIDENT FOR NOT GOING AFTER
GUN CONTROL.
HE SAID THAT YESTERDAY.
>> Steve: A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE
ALREADY STARTING TO TALK ABOUT
GUNS.
TODAY
♪ THE DAY.
>> Alisyn: SOON IT WILL BE.
WE SHOULD HAVE A NATIONAL
DIALOGUE AT SOME POINT.
>> Steve: LET'S JUST FIGURE
OUT WHAT HAPPENED.
WHY DID HE GO TO THOSE
CLASSROOMS.
>> Alisyn: IF THERE EVER IS AN
ANSWER.
WE DO HAVE A LOT OF
INFORMATION TO SHARE WITH YOU
THIS MORNING AND MANY MORE
GUESTS COMING UP.
DID THE SANDY HOOK SHOOTER
JUST SNAP OR WERE THERE
WARNING SIGNS THAT WERE
MISSED?
>> SANDY HOOK SCHOOL, CALLER
IS INDICATING SHE THINKS THERE
IS SOMEONE SHOOTING IN THE
BUILDING.
>> SANDY HOOK SCHOOL, THE
FRONT GLASS HAS BEEN OUT OF
THE SCHOOL.
THEY ARE UNSURE WHY.
I HAD ENOUGH OF FEELING
EMBARRASSED ABOUT MY SKIN.
[ Designer ]
ENOUGH OF JUST COVERING UP
MY MODERATE TO SEVERE
PLAQUE PSORIASIS.
I DECIDED ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
♪
[ Spa Lady ]
I STARTED ENBREL.
IT'S CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO PROVIDE CLEARER SKIN.
[ RV Guy ] ENBREL MAY NOT WORK
FOR EVERYONE --
AND MAY NOT CLEAR YOU
COMPLETELY,
BUT FOR MANY, IT GETS SKIN
CLEARER FAST, WITHIN 2 MONTHS,
AND KEEPS IT CLEARER
UP TO 9 MONTHS.
[ Male Announcer ]
BECAUSE ENBREL®, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL,
EVENTS INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS, LYMPHOMA,
OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING ENBREL,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START ENBREL IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON ENBREL, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING,
OR PALENESS.
IF YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH, ASK
YOUR DERMATOLOGIST ABOUT ENBREL.
I WISH I COULD KEEP IT
THIS WAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
NOW YOU CAN.
WITH THE CREST PRO-HEALTH
CLINICAL LINE.
USED TOGETHER,
THEY HELP KEEP YOUR TEETH
97% AS CLEAN
AS A DENTAL CLEANING.
THE TOOTHPASTE
ACTUALLY REDUCES PLAQUE.
AND THE RINSE REACHES ALL AREAS
AND IS CLINICALLY PROVEN TO
HELP PREVENT PLAQUE REGROWTH.
CREST PRO-HEALTH CLINICAL LINE.
TOGETHER, THEY HELP KEEP
YOUR TEETH
97% AS CLEAN
AS A DENTAL CLEANING.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
>> Brian: THIS MORNING STILL
LEARNING INFORMATION ABOUT THE
GUNMAN WHO CARRIED OUT A
CRIME.
SECOND WORST SHOOTING AT A
SCHOOL IN OUR NATION'S
HISTORY.
WHAT MAY HAVE SET HIM OFF.
WHY YESTERDAY, WHY THEN?
WHY THE WEAPONS HE USED.
ROD, FIRST OFF INSIDE THE MIND
OF THE KILLER ADAM EVIDENTLY
ACCORDING TO HIS BROTHER
AUTISTIC.
OTHERS SAY EMOTIONALLY
DISTURBED.
PAINFULLY SHY.
MOM MAY HAVE QUIT HER JOB
TEACHING AT THAT SCHOOL IN
ORDER TO SPEND TIME WITH HIM.
WE ARE STILL TRYING TO MAKE
HEADS OR TAILS OF THIS.
HOW DO YOU PUT THE PUZZLE
TOGETHER.
>> YOU ARE EXACTLY RIGHT,
BRIAN.
THE POLICE DEPARTMENT, THE
INVESTIGATORS THERE ARE TRYING
TO FIGURE OUT THE ANSWERS TO
THOSE EXACT SAME QUESTIONS.
YOU KNOW, WHAT WAS THE
CORRELATION?
HERE IS THE QUESTION.
WHAT WAS THE CORRELATION
BETWEEN THIS GUY, THAT SCHOOL
AND YESTERDAY OTHER THAN THE
MOTHER?
NOW WE ALL KNOW THAT THE
MOTHER OF THIS SHOOTER WORKED
AT THE SCHOOL.
BUT THAT'S NOT ENOUGH TO SPARK
A PERSON TO COMMIT THE
HORRIFIC ACT THAT HE COMMITTED
YESTERDAY.
SO I THINK THERE IS GOING TO
BE A LOT MORE INFORMATION,
BRIAN, THAT WE ARE GOING TO
LEARN OVER THE NEXT COUPLE OF
DAYS.
THE OTHER THING IS THE AMOUNT
OF AMMUNITION THAT THIS GUY
HAD.
NOW, IN SOME OF THE REPORTS,
BRIAN, THEY ARE ALREADY SAYING
THAT THE POLICE RECOVERED OVER
100 SHELL CASINGS AT THAT
SCHOOL.
NOW, IF THAT IS THE CASE, THIS
GUY CAME PREPARED AND AS WE
ALL KNOW HE WAS SUPPOSEDLY
WEARING A BULLET-PROOF VEST.
SO YOU KNOW HE JUST DIDN'T
WAKE UP YESTERDAY MORNING AND
SAY I'M GOING TO GO DO THIS.
I BELIEVE THIS WAS A PLANNED
EVENT.
>> IT WAS HIS MOM'S GUNS
EVIDENTLY.
THEY WERE ALL REGISTERED AND
ALL LEGAL.
THE RIFLE THAT HE HAD IN THE
CAR WAS EVIDENTLY USED FOR BIG
GAME HUNTING.
HERE IS A QUOTE FROM HIS
NEIGHBOR AND CLASSMATE TIM
DALTON NOT HIS FRIEND.
HE SAID AS HORRIBLE AS THIS
WAS, I CAN'T SAY I AM
SURPRISED.
BURN IN HELL, ADAM.
WE SEE ALL THESE RED FLAGS.
ARE THERE OTHER PEOPLE THAT
COULD SAY THAT ABOUT OTHER
POTENTIAL ASSASSINS OR IS THIS
OBVIOUSLY A GUY THAT'S CAPABLE
OF THIS?
>> WELL, THIS IS OBVIOUSLY A
GUY THAT'S CAPABLE OF IT
BECAUSE HE DID IT YESTERDAY.
HERE IS THE THING AND YOU HIT
THE NAIL ON THE HEAD.
THERE HAD TO BE WARNING SIGNS
AND APPARENTLY THE FRIEND OF
THE SHOOTER KNEW ABOUT SOME OF
THESE WARNING SIGNS BECAUSE
THAT'S WHY HE MADE THE
STATEMENT THAT HE DID.
YOU KNOW, THE POLICE AND THE
FBI RIGHT NOW, THEY ARE IN
THREE DIFFERENT STATES THIS
MORNING, BRIAN, INTERVIEWING
ASSOCIATES, RELATIVES OF THE
SHOOTER.
YOU KNOW WHAT THEY ARE TRYING
TO FIND OUT RIGHT NOW?
THEY ARE TRYING TO FIND OUT IF
THERE WERE WARNING SIGNS.
NOR ABOUT THIS GUY'S HISTORY
EVEN IF IT WAS A MENTAL ISSUE.
THEY ARE TRYING TO FIND THIS
OUT TO TRY TO DETERMINE WHAT
WAS IT THAT WAS THE SPARK THAT
IGNITED HIM YESTERDAY.
>> ROD, HERE'S THE THING.
THERE IS THE AURORA SHOOTING.
THIS GUY WAS DEFINITELY
DERANGED, SIGNS OF SHOWING
THAT HE WAS DERAKED.
PEOPLE SAY HE WAS REALLY OFF
AND HIS OWN THERAPIST SAYING
RELATIVELY SQUARED FOR HIM.
AS WE FIND OUT THAT THIS GUY
WAS A DANGER AND SCARED
EVERYBODY IN HIS NEIGHBORHOOD.
IN THE FUTURE, HOW CAN WE STOP
THE NEXT MULTIPLE SHOOTING IF
BEFORE IT HAPPENS WHILE STILL
GUARDING AGAINST PEOPLE'S
FREEDOM?
>> YOU ARE EXACTLY RIGHT.
YOU ARE GOING TO HAVE TO SPEAK
UP.
I WAS JUST TEACHING A COURSE
YESTERDAY, BRIAN, I DON'T KNOW
IF YOU HEARD, HERE IN
MINNESOTA ON ACTIVE SHOOTER
RESPONSE TRAINING TO A MAJOR
COMPANY.
AND ONE OF THE THINGS I WAS
TELLING THOSE FOLKS IS THAT
WHEN YOU SEE THESE WARNING
SIGNS, YOU CAN'T WORRY ABOUT
PROFILING.
YOU HAVE TO SPEAK UP TO
SOMEBODY.
AT THE VERY MINIMUM NOTIFY THE
POLICE DEPARTMENT SO THAT WE
CAN CHECK THESE INDIVIDUALS
OUT, BRIAN.
BECAUSE YOU DON'T WANT IT TO
BE A DAY TOO LATE.
I GUARANTEE THERE ARE PEOPLE
THAT ARE GOING TO COME FORWARD
NOW THAT IS GOING TO SAY I
WISH I WOULD HAVE SPOKE UP.
IF IT'S MEDICATION HE NEEDS TO
BE ON AND HE DOESN'T TAKE IT
AT 20 YEARS OLD THERE IS
NOTHING WE CAN DO TO MAKE HIM
TAKE IT, CORRECT?
>> NO, NO.
HE CAN BE PROBATED IF AN
INDIVIDUAL IS ORDERED BY THE
COURT TO TAKE THEIR MEDICATION
AND THEY DO NOT TAKE IT, WE
CAN GET THAT PERSON PROBATED
AND HAVE THEM FORCE THE
MEDICATION.
>> Brian: INTERESTING.
11 MINUTES BEFORE THE TOP OF
THE HOUR.
ROD WHEELER THANKS SO MUCH.
>> THANK YOU, BRIAN.
>> Brian: THANK YOU YOUR
ANALYSIS.
AS WE MOVE STRAIGHT AHEAD.
SOME PEOPLE ARE WONDERING WHAT
IS HAPPENING TO THE CULTURE OF
AMERICA?
ARE WE CHANGING OR ARE WE JUST
NOTICING MORE?
FATHER JONATHAN MORRIS HERE
LIVE NEXT.
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Sharable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>> Alisyn: YOU ARE LOOKING AT
PRAYER VIGILS HELD FOR THE
MASSACRE.
HOW CAN CHILDREN AND FAMILY
PICK UP THE PIECES AFTER ONE
OF THE DEADLIEST SHOOTINGS IN
U.S. HISTORY.
>> Steve: WE NOW TURN TO FOX
NEWS RELIGION CORRESPONDENT
JONATHAN MORRIS WHO WE TURN TO
IN TIMES LIKE THIS GOOD
MORNING.
>> GOOD MORNING, THANK YOU.
>> Steve: WHAT DO YOU THINK.
>> CERTAINLY THERE IS NO
EXPLANATION THAT WE CAN GIVE
TO WHY GOD ALLOWS THIS TO
HAPPEN.
WHY IT DID HAPPEN.
WE DO KNOW IT'S NOT A
SENSELESS ACT LIKE WE HEAR
FROM SO MANY POLITICIANS AND
EVEN SOMETIMES RELIGIOUS
LEADERS IT'S NOT SENSELESS,
COMBINATION MENTAL ILLNESS,
FREE CHOICE, DECIDING TO GO
AND DO SOMETHING VERY VERY BAD
THIRD I THINK THE POWER OF
EVIL.
THE POWER OF EVIL WHEN WE
ALLOW OURSELVES OR BECAUSE OF
MENTAL ILLNESS TO GET INVOLVED
IN OUR MIND AND IN OUR HEART
OF SUCH A TERRIBLE TERRIBLE
THING LIKE KILLING SOMEBODY,
THE DEVIL, IN MY OPINION, GETS
INVOLVED AND THE POWER OF EVIL
TAKES OVER.
>> Alisyn: WHAT ARE WE
SUPPOSED TO DO ABOUT THIS.
YOU WROTE A BOOK A COUPLE OF
YEARS AGO ABOUT SUFFERING AND
DEALING WITH TRAGEDY AND WHAT
PRIESTS ALWAYS SAY IS THAT GOD
CAN'T PREVENT THESE THINGS
FROM HAPPENING BUT GOD IS WITH
YOU.
THAT'S NOT ENOUGH.
>> THAT'S NOT ENOUGH.
WE CAN NEVER GIVE A PERFECT
EXPLANATION.
GOD CAN'T STOP IT.
HE CAN'T K. IF HE WANTS.
HE USUALLY DOES NOT.
THEN WE NO LONGER WOULD HAVE
FREE WILL.
WE -8D BE REBOTS.
WE COULDN'T DO BAD BUT WE ALSO
COULDN'T LOVE.
THERE WOULD BE NO RELATIONSHIP
MAN OR GOD EVEN AMONG
OURSELVES IF THERE WAS NO FREE
WILL.
BUT, WHEN THERE ARE CHILDREN
KILLED, WE SAY WELL WHY, AT
LEAST IN THIS INSTANCE DIDN'T
GOD INTERVENE.
IF THERE IS NO SUCH THING AS
HEAVEN.
ETERNAL LIFE THEN YOU HAVE TO
SAY THAT GOD IS AN EVIL, EVIL
BEING.
I BELIEVE GOD BRINGS OUT A
GREATER GOOD OUT OF EVERY
SINGLE INSTANCE OF EVIL AND
SUFFERING IN THIS WORLD THAT'S
WHAT I HAVE WROTE ABOUT.
BUT SOMETIMES THAT GREATER
GOOD ONLY COMES OUT IN
ETERNITY.
WHAT DO PARENTS DO RIGHT NOW
OR WHAT DO WE DO FOR THE
PARENTS?
WE HUG THEM.
THEY HUG EACH OTHER.
PART OF GOD'S SOLUTION TO THIS
GREAT EVIL THAT WAS CARRIED
OUT NOT BY GOD BUT BY A HUMAN
BEING IS OUR LOVE FOR ONE
ANOTHER.
OUR LOVE FOR ANOTHER IS WHAT
WE CAN GIVE TO THESE FAMILIES
RIGHT NOW.
AND THERE IS LOVE BEING SENT
FROM ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY
RIGHT NOW.
>> Steve: YESTERDAY WAS A BIG
DAY FOR PRAYER ASIDE FROM THE
FACT THAT PEOPLE WOULD
SPONTANEOUSLY SEE THE EVIL
IMAGES AND DO THAT ON THEIR
OWN.
LAST NIGHT THE CONNECTICUT
GOVERNOR MALOY SAID ADD THESE
FAMILIES IN YOUR PRAYERS.
SAY A PRAY FOR THE CHILDREN.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
ABSOLUTELY.
I GET THAT ALL THE TIME COMING
FROM PEOPLE WHO ARE JUST
WANTING TO BE A PART OF IT.
I PUT A VERY SIMPLE TWEET OUT
YESTERDAY SAYING I LIVE ONLY
60 MILES AWAY FROM THIS
TRAGEDY.
IF ANYBODY NEEDS SPIRITUAL
GUIDANCE OR COMFORT IF I CAN
BE OF HELP.
ALL OF A SUDDEN IT GETS
RETWEETED ALL OVER THE PLACE.
ONE OF THE FAMILIES CONTACTED
ME.
SOMEBODY PUT KNEE IN CONTACT
WITH THE PRIEST AT THAT
PERISH.
AMAZING ABILITY NOW TO BE ABLE
TO COME TOGETHER EVEN USING
NEW TECHNOLOGY.
>> THAT'S REALLY NICE.
THE RAP ON SOCIAL MEDIA IS
THAT IT SORT OF SEPARATES US.
YOU HAVE VIRTUAL FRIENDS BUT
TO BE ABLE TO HELP PEOPLE AT
THAT DISTANCE IS ALSO REALLY
NICE.
WE WILL CHECK BACK IN WITH
YOU, FATHER.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR BEING
HERE.
>> THANKS FOR HAVING ME.
>> Steve: WE WILL RETURN IN
TWO MINUTES.
YOU ARE WATCHING THE FOX NEWS
CHANNEL.
I'M DOING MY OWN SLEEP STUDY.
ADVIL PM® OR TYLENOL PM.
THE ADVIL PM® GUY
IS SPENDING LESS TIME
LYING AWAKE
WITH ANNOYING ACHES AND PAINS
AND MORE TIME ASLEEP.
ADVIL PM®. THE DIFFERENCE
IS A BETTER NIGHT'S SLEEP.
WITH ANNOYING ACHES AND PAINS
AND MORE TIME ASLEEP.
It's hard to see opportunity
in today's challenging
environment.
Unless you have the right
perspective.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
has the vision
and experience to look beyond
the obvious.
We'll uncover opportunities,
find hidden risk,
and make success a reality.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
But when I was in an accident...
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
So I never missed a beat.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN,
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS
OLD.
[SIGH]
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM, BIRTHDAYS,
GRADUATIONS, WEDDINGS, KIDS OF
THEIR OWN.
[SIGH]
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS, MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES TO HELPING
THEIR CHILDREN TO FULFILL
THEIR DREAMS.
SO OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN TODAY
FOR THE PARENTS AND
GRANDPARENTS, SISTERS AND
BROTHERS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN AND FOR THE FAMILIES
OF THE ADULTS WHO WERE LOST.
>> Steve: GOOD MORNING,
EVERYBODY, WELCOME TO SPECIAL
EDITION OF "FOX & FRIENDS."
BRIAN AND I JOIN ALI TODAY FOR
THIS SPECIAL COVERAGE.
THIS MORNING AS THE WORLD
WAKES UP AND LOOKS AT THE 26
DEAD THERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, PEOPLE ARE ASKING
THE QUESTION WHY.
WHY DID THAT 20-YEAR-OLD KID
GET UP YESTERDAY MORNING,
MURDER HIS MOTHER AND THEN
DRIVE TO THE SCHOOL SHE WORKED
IN AND KILLED 20 KIDS?
>> OR WAS HE PLANNING THIS FOR
A LONG TIME FROM THE AMMO TO
THE GUNS.
HE DIDN'T MISS.
WORD IS IN THREE MINUTES, THE
GUY DIDN'T MISS.
AND HE SPREAD OVER 100 ROUNDS.
>> DEADLY ACCURATE.
ONLY ONE PERSON WAS INJURED.
EVERYBODY ELSE WAS FATALLY
SHOT.
>> THATS WHAT A TEACHER THAT
THREW HERSELVES IN FRONT OF A
CLASSROOM AND A DOOR AND GOT
SHOT IN THE ARM AND THE LEG.
>> Alisyn: HOPELY WE WILL GET
ANSWERS.
THAT'S WHAT EVERYONE BEGS FOR
AFTER SOMETHING LIKE THIS
HAPPENS FIGURE OUT WHY IT
HAPPENS SO WE CAN PREVENT THEY M
IN THE FUTURE.
CAN I TELL YOU FROM COVERING
CRIME FOR FIVE YEARS AND
TALKING TO MURDERERS IN THEIR
PRISON CELLS IT'S A FOOL'S
ERRAND.
THEY DON'T HAVE GOOD
EXPLANATION THAT END UP MAKING
SENSE.
>> Steve: THAT'S THE KEY.
WE WANT AN EASY ANSWER.
WE WANT TO KNOW WHY HE DID IT.
BUT WHEN YOU'RE CRAZY.
WHEN YOU ARE EVIL AS HE SURELY
WAS, WE MAY NEVER KNOW.
>> Brian: RIGHT.
>> Alisyn: WE DO HAVE A LOT
MORE INFORMATION FOR YOU THIS
MORNING.
WE ARE GLAD YOU ARE WITH US.
PETER DOOCY IS LIVE IN NEW
HAVEN, CONNECTICUT WITH THE
LATEST THAT'S HAPPENED
OVERNIGHT.
>> ALISYN, ALL NIGHT LONG THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER'S OFFICE
WORKED TO POSITIVELY IDENTIFY
THE VICTIMS.
WE'RE TOLD THAT THERE WAS A
TEMPORARY MORGUE SET UP SOME
PLACE INSIDE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THAT'S WHERE AUTHORITIES TOOK
THE YOUNG VICTIMS AND THEY
PHOTOGRAPHED THEM SO THAT THEY
COULD SHOW THOSE PHOTOGRAPHS
TO THEIR PARENTS.
ALL 20 CHILDREN WHO WERE
KILLED WERE BETWEEN THE AGES
OF 5 AND 10.
IT IS A NIGHTMARE HERE IN
NEWTOWN FOR EVERYONE WHO IS
EVEN IN THE MOST SLIGHT WAY
INVOLVED.
NOW, THE 20-YEAR-OLD MASS
MURDERER, ADAM LANZA USED AT
LEAST THREE GUNS YESTERDAY.
THEY WERE ALL LEGALLY
REGISTERED TO HIS MOTHER NANCY
LANZA, ADAM SHOT HIS MOM NANCY
BEFORE HEADING TO THIS SCHOOL
AND HE DID MOST OF HIS KILLING
IN JUST TWO CLASSROOMS.
>> THE INDIVIDUAL THAT I HAVE
ON THE PHONE IS CONTINUING TO
HEAR WHAT HE BELIEVES TO BE
GUNFIRE.
>> UNITS IN THE SCHOOL.
I HAVE GOT BODIES HERE.
>> ONCE THE SHOOTING STARTED.
WE'RE TOLD THAT STUDENTS HEARD
SCREAMING OVER THE SCHOOL'S
INTERCOM SYSTEM.
TEACHERS EVENTUALLY EVACUATED
STUDENTS TO A NEARBY FIREHOUSE
AND PARENTS WERE TOLD, MANY
PARENTS, THAT THEIR KIDS
WERE -- THAT THERE WERE
CHILDREN AT THE FIREHOUSE.
THEY DIDN'T KNOW IF THEIR
CHILD MADE IT TO THE
FIREHOUSE.
A LOT OF THESE PARENTS JUST
KNEW THAT THE CHILDREN WHO
MADE IT WERE AT THE FIREHOUSE
AND THEY WERE SHOWING UP NOT
KNOWING IF THEIR CHILD WAS
ALIVE OR DEAD.
>> ARE YOU TRYING TO FIND YOUR
CHILD, MA'AM?
>> NO.
MY GIRLFRIEND'S DAUGHTER, MY
BABYSITTER.
HER AND MY LITTLE DAUGHTER ARE
LIKE BEST FRIENDS AND THEY
JUST TOLD US GO TO MALOY.
THEY TOLD US IF YOU CAN'T FIND
YOUR CHILDREN, THEY ARE DEAD
IN THE BUILDING.
>> IN CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR
DANIEL MALOY SAID EVIL VISITED
THIS COMMUNITY YESTERDAY AND
FROM EVERYTHING THAT WE HAVE
HEARD AND EVERYTHING THAT WE
HAVE SEEN, HE WAS SPOT ON BACK
TO YOU IN NEW YORK.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THERE IS A FULLER PICTURE OF
WHO ADAM LANZA WAS.
THERE IS INFORMATION COMING
OUT ABOUT THIS GUNMAN.
GREW UP IN NEWTOWN, DIVORCED
IN 2008 OR 2008.
HE THEN LIVED WITH HIS MOTHER
APPARENTLY ALONE IN NEWTOWN
BECAUSE HIS BROTHER LIVED IN
NEW JERSEY.
>> SHE WORKED FOR THE SCHOOL
SYSTEM ALTHOUGH IT'S UNCERTAIN
EXACTLY WHAT HER STATUS WAS AT
THE TIME OF THE MURDER.
>> WAS SHE A SUBSTITUTE?
WAS SHE PART TIME?
>> AN AIDE?
>> Brian: WAS SHE RETIRED OR
DID SHE STEP ASIDE TO SPEND
MORE TIME WITH HER TROUBLED
SON?
>> Alisyn: THAT WAS ONE REPORT
AS WELL.
THEN THERE WERE GUNS THAT WERE
FOUND AT THE SCENE AND THEY
APPARENTLY WERE REGISTERED TO
HIS MOTHER, NANCY LANZA.
THAT'S AN INTERESTING POINT
RIGHT THERE.
BECAUSE, YOU KNOW, OBVIOUSLY
YOUR RELATIONSHIP IS GUNS IS
DIFFERENT DEPENDING ON WHERE
YOU LIVE IN THIS COUNTRY.
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT THERE
WAS LIKE ONE CRIME THERE SINCE
2010.
ONE VIOLENT CRIME.
AGAIN, IN CONNECTICUT, THESE
NOT -- THIS IS NOT TEXAS OR
THE EAST COAST NEAR NEW YORK
WE HAVE A DIFFERENT
RELATIONSHIP WITH ONES.
FOR A WOMAN TO HAVE THREE GUNS
ONE OF THEM POSSIBLY THIS
SEMIAUTOMATIC THAT HE USED
IT'S INTERESTING THAT SHE HAD
THESE GUNS.
WHO KNOWS WHY BUT IT'S ALSO
POSSIBLE THAT HE HIMSELF WAS
TROUBLED.
THERE ARE LOTS OF REPORTS FROM
NEIGHBORS THAT THE SON WHO
LIVED WITH HER ADAM WAS A
TROUBLED KID SOMEHOW.
>> Brian: AS EARLY AS 5 YEARS
OLD IN TERMS OF THE WEAPONS HE
USED A GLOCK, AN SIG SOWER, IF
I HAVE SAID THAT WRONG EXCUSE
ME.
A BUSH RIFLE WAS LEFT IN THE
CAR.
>> AS CAN YOU SEE FROM THAT
GRAPHIC BROTHER TOLD
AUTHORITIES THAT HE WAS
AUTISTIC AND SOME OF THE
NEIGHBORS SAID YEAH, HE WAS
NOT WELL.
>> Alisyn: WANT TO CLARIFY
THAT AS WELL.
HIS BROTHER SAID AUTISTIC AND
SAID I THINK HE HAD AS
BERGER'S SYSTEM WHICH IS A
VERY DIFFERENT PLACE ON THE
SPECTRUM FOR AUTISM.
VERY HIGH FUNCTIONING.
DESCRIBED AS A GENIUS.
DESCRIBED AS A GREAT STUDENT.
DESCRIBED AS A COMPUTER NERD
AND HE HAD A PERSONALITY
DISORDER.
>> Steve: WHATEVER IT WAS, HE
WAS EVIL YESTERDAY.
ANY TIME YOU START THE DAY BY
MURDERING YOUR MOTHER AND THEN
TAKING HER CAR TO THE SCHOOL
AND, OF COURSE NOW WE ARE
TRYING TO PIECE IT ALL
TOGETHER AND TRYING IT TALK TO
AS MANY PEOPLE INVOLVED AS WE
CAN.
>> Alisyn: NEXT GUEST LIVES
THROUGH THE MOST TERRIFYING
MOMENTS OF HIS LIFE YESTERDAY
WHEN HE HEARS GUNSHOTS COMING
FROM HIS LITTLE SISTER'S
SCHOOL FROM HIS HOME.
THEY RAN THERE AND ARRIVED
BEFORE MANY OF THE FIRST
RESPONDERS.
PLEASE TELL US WHAT HAPPENED
YESTERDAY AT 9:30 THAT YOU
STARTED TO HEAR.
>> WELL, BASICALLY I WAS AT
HOME FROM SCHOOL THAT DAY.
WE HEARD -- MY NEIGHBOR AND I
HEARD TWO GUNSHOTS ECHO
BECAUSE IT'S A VERY OPEN AREA.
AS SOON AS WE HEARD THE ECHOS
WE RAN TO THE SCHOOL WITH MY
MOM TO SEE WHAT WAS HAPPENING.
AND THAT'S WHERE WE SAW THE
STATE TROOPERS THERE.
>> Brian: WHAT TIME WAS THAT
ABOUT, DO YOU KNOW?
>> I WANT TO SAY ABOUT 9:45.
>> Steve: YOU GOT THERE BEFORE
THE FIRST RESPONDERS, RIGHT?
>> WELL, THERE WERE SOME FIRST
RESPONDERS THERE.
THERE WERE THE LOCAL POLICE
AND THERE WERE SOME STATE
TROOPERS.
BUT IT WAS NOT A HEAVILY
SECURED AREA WHEN I WAS THERE.
I WAS THERE VERY EARLY IN THE
RUNNING.
>> DID YOU GO TO THE FRONT
DOOR MERGINM?
>> EXCUSE ME.
>>
>> DID YOU GO TO THE FRONT
DOOR OF THE SCHOOL.
>> I WAS ABLE TO SEE IT BUT I
DID NOT GO, YOU KNOW, TO THE
FRONT DOOR, NO.
>> Alisyn: MERGIM DESCRIBE THE
SCENE WHEN YOU ARRIVED AT THE
SCHOOL.
>> THERE WEREN'T A LOT OF
PARENTS THERE YET EITHER.
WHEN I WAS THERE IT WAS NOT
VERY HEAVILY GUARDED BUT THERE
WERE STATE TROOPERS.
AND, YOU KNOW, THE FIRST THING
I SAW WAS TWO LITTLE GIRLS
BEING CARRIED OUT FROM THE
SCENE BY STATE TROOPERS.
IT WAS JUST HORRENDOUS.
>> MERGIM THAT'S THE REASON
YOU RAN TO THE SCHOOL WILL
WILL IS BECAUSE YOUR LITTLE
SISTER GOES TO THAT SCHOOL AND
YOU DIDN'T KNOW AT THAT TIME
IF SHE WAS OKAY.
>> CORRECT.
I MEAN, THERE WAS ABOUT A 20
MINUTE TIME SPAN BETWEEN THE
TIME I SAW THOSE TWO LITTLE
GIRLS AND I SAW MY SISTER.
AND, YOU KNOW, THOSE WERE JUST
WORST 20 MINUTES OF MY LIFE.
I JUST CAN'T PUT IT INTO
WORDS.
>> Steve: HOW DID IT WORK?
ONCE THEY STARTED TO SECURE
THE AREA, HOW QUICKLY DID THEY
GET THE REST OF THE KIDS, LIKE
YOUR SISTER OUT OF THE
BUILDING HEADED OFF TO THE
NEARBY FIRE STATION?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, I JUST WANT
TO PUT OUT THERE, YOU KNOW,
THE POLICE THEY DID AN AWESOME
JOB, GREAT JOB, BLESS THEM.
THEY GOT THE CHILDREN OUT AS
QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE.
AND, YOU KNOW, THE EFFORTS ARE
QUICK AND THE CHILDREN CAME
OUT SAFELY.
THEY WERE MOVING, THEY WERE
CRYING BUT THE MOST IMPORTANT
THING IS THAT THOSE CHILDREN
THAT LEFT THE SCHOOL, THEY
WERE SAFE AND I HAVE TO
COMMEND EVERYONE INVOLVED FOR
THAT BECAUSE IT WAS AN AMAZING
EFFORT.
>> Alisyn: MERGIM ONE OF THE
MOST HEART BREAKING VISION
YESTERDAY AND IDEAS CONCEPTS
IS THAT ALL OF THESE PARENTS
WERE SHOWING UP AT THE SCHOOL
AND THEY DIDN'T KNOW IF THEIR
KIDS WERE DEAD OR ALIVE.
DID YOU SEE PARENTS SHOWING UP
WHO COULDN'T FIND THEIR
CHILDREN?
>> YOU KNOW, THERE WERE
PARENTS THAT SHOWED UP THAT
WERE NOT ABLE TO FIND THEIR
CHILDREN, BUT MANY OF WHICH I
KNOW WERE ABLE TO FIND THEIR
CHILDREN.
BUT I DO KNOW SOME PEOPLE,
SOME PEOPLE WHO GO TO SCHOOL
WITH ME THAT UNFORTUNATELY
WERE NOT AS LUCKY AND IT'S
JUST REALLY A SHAME.
IT'S A SHAME.
>> MERGIM, FIRST OFF, YOUR
SISTER, HOW IS SHE AND WHAT
DID SHE TELL YOU HAPPENED FROM
HER PERSPECTIVE?
>> WELL, THANKFULLY SHE IS
FINE.
UNFORTUNATELY, I MEAN SHE IS
OBVIOUSLY A LITTLE SHAKEN UP
JUST LIKE EVERYONE ELSE IS.
BUT, WHAT SHE TOLD ME WAS
THAT, YOU KNOW, IN THE MORNING
SHE WAS IN ART CLASS.
AND THE INTERCOM CAME ON WHERE
SHE HEARD A SCREAM AND A
BULLET.
AND THAT'S WHEN THE SCHOOL
WENT INTO LOCKDOWN AND WHAT
ULTIMATELY HAPPENED WAS
BECAUSE SHE WAS IN THE ART
CLASS THEY LOCKED THE DOORS.
ONE OF THE DOORS IN THE ART
CLASS DID NOT LOCK ACCORDING
TO WHAT SHE SAID.
SO THEY HAD TO GO INTO A --
SOME SORT OF SMALL ROOM, A
CLOSET.
I'M NOT EXACTLY SURE HOW SHE
DETAILED IT BUT THEY HAD TO GO
TO A SMALL ROOM AND STAY
QUIET.
HER RECOUNT OF IT WAS REALLY
HORRENDOUS.
>> Steve: I CAN IMAGINE.
I KNOW YOU GO TO THE HIGH
SCHOOL THERE IN NEWTOWN NOW.
YOU DID GO TO THAT SCHOOL.
DID YOU KNOW THE PRINCIPAL?
>> WELL, THE PRINCIPAL WAS
RELATIVELY KNEW THERE.
DID I NOT KNOW HER.
BUT I KNOW MANY WHO DID KNOW
HER.
AND I HEARD SHE WAS AN
AMAZING, WONDERFUL WOMAN.
AND SHE WILL REALLY BE MISSED.
SHE IS A TRUE HERO TO NEW
TOWN.
SHE REALLY IS.
>> Steve: IT IS VERY NICE OF
TO YOU HAVE THOSE KIND WORDS
ABOUT HER.
SHE DID LOSE HER LIFE.
AND FOR YOU TO SAY THE NICE
THINGS AS WELL ABOUT THE FIRST
RESPONDERS.
YOU WERE THERE AND SAW WITH
YOUR OWN TWO EYES.
>> YEP.
>> Bill: THANKS SO MUCH FOR
JOINING US THIS MORNING.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Brian: BEST OF LUCK TO YOU
AND YOUR FAMILY.
>> Steve: CAN YOU IMAGINE WHAT
HE DETAILED.
LOCKED DOORS BUT ONE OF THE
DOORS COULDN'T LOCK.
CAN YOU IMAGINE?
>> Alisyn: ALL STUDENTS HAVE
STORIES OF BEING COMPLETELY
TERRORIZED BECAUSE THEY COULD
HEAR WHAT WAS GOING ON IN THE
HALLWAY AND THE SHOUTING AND
THE GUN SHOTS.
THEY TRIED TO FIND SOME SORT
OF SAFE AREA IF IT WAS A
BATHROOM OR A CLOSET.
THESE KIDS WILL BE TRAUMATIZED
FOR A LONG TIME, IF NOT A A
LIFELONG ALTERING MOMENT.
>> Brian: WE WILL TALK TO A
CHILD PSYCHOLOGIST SHORTLY AND
THAT WILL BE COMING YOUR WAY.
MEANWHILE, IS THERE A WAY TO
PREVENT SOMETHING LIKE THIS
FROM HAPPENING EVER AGAIN OR
ARE WE JUST HELPLESS TO THIS
KIND OF VIOLENCE?
THAT STORY AND THAT ANGLE OF
THE STORY IS NEXT.
TWINS. I DIDN'T SEE THEM COMING.
I HAVE OBLIGATIONS. CUTE
OBLIGATIONS, BUT OBLIGATIO.
I NEED TO RETHINK THE
CORE OF MY PORTFOLIO.
WHAT I REALLY NEED IS SLEEP.
INTRODUCING THE ISHARES CORE,
BUILDING BLOCKS FOR THE
HEART OF YOUR PORTFOLIO.
FIND OUT WHY 9 OUT OF 10
LARGE PROFESSIONAL INVESTORS
CHOOSE ISHARES FOR THEIR ETFS.
ISHARES BY BLACKROCK.
CALL 1-800-ISHARES FOR A
PROSPECTUS WHICH INCLUDES
INVESTMENT OBJECTIVES,
RISKS, CHARGES AND EXPENSES.
READ AND CONSIDER
IT CAREFULLY
BEFORE INVESTING.
RISK INCLUDES POSSIBLE
LOSS OF PRINCIPAL.
♪
[ engine revs ]
[ Male Announcer ]
OH WHAT FUN IT IS TO RIDE.
GET THE MERCEDES-BENZ
ON YOUR WISH LIST
AT THE WINTER EVENT GOING ON
NOW THROUGH DECEMBER 31ST.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
E350 FOR $579 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
WE DON'T LET FREQUENT HEARTBURN
COME BETWEEN US
AND WHAT WE LOVE.
SO IF YOU'RE ONE OF THEM PEOPLE
WHO GETS HEARTBURN
AND THEN TREATS DAY AFR DAY...
BLOCK THE ACID WITH PRILOSEC OTC
AND DON'T GET HEARTBURN
IN THE FIRST PLACE!
[ Male Announcer ]
E PILL EACHMORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBUR
AND DON'T GET HEARTBURN
IN THE FIRST PLACE!
[ Female Announcer ] SOME
PEOPLE LIKE TO PRETEND A FLOOD
COULD NEVER HAPPEN TO THEM.
AND THAT THEIR HOMEOWNERS
INSURANCE PROTECTS THEM.
[ THUNDER CRASHES ]
IT DOESN'T.
STOP PRETENDING.
ONLY FLOOD INSURANCE
COVERS FLOODS.
♪
VISIT FLOODSMART.GOV/PRETEND
TO LEARN YOUR RISK.
>> Brian: SMALL TOWN
CONNECTICUT CAME UNTHINKABLE
SCENE OF A TRAGEDY.
A YOUNG MAN GUNS DOWN 20 KIDS
BETWEEN THE AGES OF A AND 10.
20 WERE CHILDREN.
WHAT STEPS CAN WE TAKE AS A
SOCIETY TO PREVENT ANOTHER ACT
OF VIOLENCE LIKE THIS IF WE
CAN PREVENT ANOTHER ACT OF
VIOLENCE LIKE THIS.
JOINING US NOW ARTHUR AIDALA.
YOU BELIEVE WE HAVE TO STUDY
THE KILLER IN ORDER TO PREVENT
SOMETHING LIKE THIS TO HAPPEN
GOTTEN ON LESSEN THE CHANCES.
>> ARE YOU ARE RIGHT.
EVEN TO HAVE A SHOT OF
PREVENTING SOMETHING LIKE
THIS.
THANK GOD IT'S SO RARE THAT
ANYTHING LIKE THIS HAPPENS.
AND I THINK WHAT WE HAVE TO
MAKE SURE IS THAT THERE IS NO
KNEE JERK REACTIONS TO THIS.
THE THREE AREAS THAT I
ANTICIPATE ARE GOING TO BE
STUDIED HERE OR LOOKED AT IS
NUMBER ONE, OBVIOUSLY, GUN
CONTROL AND THE PROS AND CONS
AND YOU ARE GOING TO HEAR BOTH
SIDES OF THE ARGUMENT.
NUMBER TWO, IF THIS -- I DON'T
KNOW WHAT YOU WANT TO CALL
THEM HAD AUTISM OR AS
BERGERES, PEOPLE ARE LOOKING
TO LOOK AT HOW WE TREAT PEOPLE
WHO WE KNOW HAVE SOME SORT OF
A MENTAL DISEASE OR DETECT DEE
FECKET OR DISABILITY AND
ESPECIALLY IF THERE ARE
WARNING SIGNS.
SOMEBODY SAYS I WANT TO KILL
PEOPLE.
WHAT DO WE DO AND THEN THE
THIRD ONE OBVIOUSLY IS GOING
TO BE SCHOOL SECURITY.
I MEAN, BRIAN, DO WE WANT TO
MAKE A LITTLE SCHOOL A LITTLE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL OR LITTLE
QUIET SLEEPY TOWN INTO AN
AIRPORT WHERE PEOPLE ANYONE
WHO WANTS TO JUST GET THROUGH
THE THRESHOLD OF THE DOOR HAS
TO STRIP DOWN?
BECAUSE LET ME JUST TELL YOU
THAT'S WHAT HAPPENED AFTER
SEPTEMBER 11TH LIKE ON
THURSDAY I HAD TO GO TO THE
U.S. ATTORNEY'S OFFICE IN NEW
JERSEY NEWARK, NEW JERSEY, I'M
A LAWYER, I'M FINGERPRINTED.
I HAD TO TAKE OFF MY SHOES MY
BELT MY HAT, MY JACKET.
IT'S A DIFFERENT WAY TO LIVE.
>> Brian: THERE ARE METAL
DETECTORS IN SCHOOLS IN NEW
YORK CITY.
>> YOU DON'T THINK ABOUT IT IN
A SLEEPY TOWN LIKE THAT.
>> Bill: PUT A WILL THE OF
MONEY INTO A SECURITY SYSTEM.
>> THEY ALREADY DO.
>> Brian: WHY NOT PUT A PERSON
THERE AND GIVE THEM PERMISSION
TO BE ARMED.
ARE YOU GOING TO ARM 135,000
SCHOOLS ACROSS THE COUNTRY?
>> BRIAN, LET'S FACE IT, IF
THERE WAS A GUY THAT WAS ARMED
THERE HE WOULD BE DEAD.
THEY KNEW THIS I HAD CAN I
BELIEVE.
HE WAS A FAMILIAR FACE.
HE WAS ABLE TO OPEN THE DOOR,
BOOM, HE WOULD HAVE SKILLED
THE SECURITY GUARD RIGHT AWAY.
THAT ONE GUY WITH ONE GUN IN
THAT I WOULD ABOUTING DOESN'T
SEEM LIKE IT WAS GOING TO STOP
ANYTHING.
>> Brian: YOU ARE SAYING OR
THEIR IF YOU WERE IN CONTROL
OF WHAT HAPPENED HERE YOU
WOULD LOOK AT THE OREGON
SHOOTING MALL LAST WEEK.
LOOK AT THE AURORA MOVIE
THEATER.
YOU WOULD LOOK AT THE KILLING
OF ALL THOSE PEOPLE AND
WOUNDING OF GABRIEL GIFFORDS.
>> CONGRESSMAN WHICH IS
BASICALLY WHAT THE PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED STATES SAID
YESTERDAY.
WE HAVE TO FIGURE OUT A WAY TO
STOP THIS FROM HAPPENING.
>> Brian: THOSE GUNS
REPORTEDLY ALL LEGALLY
REGISTERED TO THE MOM.
>> WHICH IS GOING TO IGNITE A
WHOLE -- AGAIN, IT WAS A KNEE
JERK REACTION.
WITHIN MOMENTS OF THIS EVIL,
WITHIN MOMENTS OF THIS TERROR
PEOPLE STARTED TWEETING THEIR
RESPECTIVE GUN CONTROL, GUN
THIS, PROGUN, ANTIGUN
POSITION.
GIVE ME A BREAK, FOLKS.
SETTLE DOWN, BREATHE, MOURN,
LET'S STUDY, LET'S FIGURE
THINGS OUT BEFORE YOU REACH A
CONCLUSION ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
HERE.
>> Brian: OF COURSE YOU ARE
REFERRING ONE OF THE PEOPLE IS
MAYOR BLOOMBERG.
>> WHEN I WAS WITH YOU
YESTERDAY AFTERNOON, YOU KNOW,
WE WERE TALKING I HEARD ABOUT
A WHOLE BUNCH OF DIFFERENT
PEOPLE.
ENOUGH, LET'S JUST.
ANY TIME ANYTHING LIKE THIS
HAPPENS, YOU NEED TO TAKE A
PROFESSIONAL, INTELLIGENT
APPROACH AND ABSORB IT ALL AND
DIGEST IT AND THEN FIGURE OUT
WHAT THE REMEDY IS IF THERE IS
REMEDY, BRIAN.
HORRIBLE CAR ACCIDENTS ALL THE
TIME.
ALL THE TIME THEY KILL YOUNG
KIDS ALL THE TIME.
DO WE AUTOMATICALLY SAY LET'S
STOP DRIVING?
DO YOU KNOW THEY ALREADY HAVE
CARS THAT DRIVE THEMSELVES
THAT ARE CRASH-PROOF AND WE
DON'T HAVE THEM OUT THERE.
SLOW DOWN, EVERYONE.
THERE IS A LOT OF PAIN HERE.
LET'S GET THROUGH THE PAIN AND
FIGURE OUT WHAT'S GOING ON.
>> Brian: SLOW DOWN AND FIGURE
OUT WHAT'S GOING ON AND DON'T
DISMISS IT AND SAY THAT KID IS
NUTS.
THAT'S THE FLIP SIDE.
>> CORRECT.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
19 MINUTES AFTER THE HOUR.
HARD TO IMAGINE WHAT THE
FAMILY OF THE VICTIMS ARE
GOING THROUGH RIGHT NOW.
OUR NEXT GUEST UNDERSTANDS
THAT PAIN ALL TOO WELL.
SHE LOST HER DAUGHTER IN
COLUMBINE.
initiated.
Neural speeds
increasing to 4G LTE.
Brain upgrading to a quad-core
processor.
Predictive intelligence
with Google Now complete.
Introducing DROID DNA by HTC.
It's not an upgrade
to your phone.
It's an upgrade to yourself.
>> Steve: IT'S HARD FOR ANY
PARENT TO IMAGINE WHAT THE
MOMS AND DADS OF THE VICTIMS
IN CONNECT CONSULT AT THE
SCHOOL ARE GOING THROUGH RIGHT
NOW.
OUR NEXT GUEST UNDERSTANDS
THEIR POSITION AND PAIN ALL
TOO WELL.
BETH LOST DAUGHTER RACHEL JOY
SCOTT IN THE COLUMBINE
SHOOTING IN COLORADO AND HER
SON CRAIG WITNESSED THE
TRAGEDY AND SURVIVED.
SHE JOINS US THIS MORNING FROM
DENVER.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU, BETH.
>> GOOD MORNING.
>> YOU KNOW, IT'S HARD FOR US
LOOKING INTO IMAGINE WHAT
THOSE PARENTS ARE GOING
THROUGH.
YOU KNOW, WE JUST HEARD FROM
OUR CORRESPONDENT THEY HAVE
APPARENTLY SET UP A MAKESHIFT
MORGUE AND NOW THE PARENTS ARE
STARTING TO IDENTIFY THEIR
CHILDREN BY PICTURES.
YOU WENT THROUGH THIS A NUMBER
OF YEARS AGO.
>>
>> I DID.
>> WHAT ARE THEY GOING
THROUGH?
THAT TIME OF WAITING THERE IS
MIXED FEELINGS.
YOU HAVE SOME HOPE.
AND YET, THERE IS THIS
IMPENDING DOOM THAT BECAUSE
YOU HAVEN'T HEARD FROM YOUR
CHILD OR THERE IS NO NEWS
ABOUT THEM THAT THE WORST IS
TO BE EXPECTED AND FOR US IT
TOOK EXACTLY 24 HOURS FOR WHEN
RACHEL PASSED AWAY TO GET A
CALL FROM THE CORONER.
WE DIDN'T IDENTIFY HER.
THEY IDENTIFIED HER THROUGH
SOME FINGERPRINTS THAT I HAD
MADE UP AS MY KIDS WERE
LITTLE.
AND SHE WAS IDENTIFIED THAT
WAY.
>> JUST THE WAITING, YOU SAY
THAT IT TOOK YOU 24 HOURS.
THEY KNOW, YOU KNOW, ALL THE
OTHER PARENTS WERE REUNITED
WITH THEIR CHILDREN.
THEY KNOW WHAT HAPPENED TO
THEM AND YET THEY HAVE GOT TO
AWAIT FORMAL WORD.
>> YEAH.
THAT WAS THE HARDEST PART.
FOR US WE WERE TOLD THAT
EVENING TO GO HOME AND THAT NO
MORE INFORMATION WAS FORTH
COMING.
THAT WAS JUST ABOUT THE
CRUELEST THING WE COULD HAVE
BEEN TOLD AT THAT POINT IN
TIME BECAUSE THEY WEREN'T
RELEASING NAMES OF VICTIMS.
BUT THERE WERE STUDENTS THAT
HAD SEEN RACHEL'S BODY SO WE
WERE GETTING RECORDS REPORTS
FROM THEM EVEN THOUGH IT WAS
VERIFIED BY AUTHORITIES.
IT'S A SLEEPLESS NIGHT.
IT'S THE SADDEST THING.
YOU WANT TO HOLD ON TO HOPE
BUT IN YOUR MIND YOU KNOW THAT
IT'S GONE.
>> BETH, I UNDERSTAND YOU TOLD
ONE OF OUR PRODUCERS THAT THE
PARENTS OF THE CHILDREN WHO
WERE LOST YESTERDAY THEY ARE
NOT GOING TO KNOW WHAT HIT
THEM FOR A WHILE.
>> THEY WON'T.
I BELIEVE IT WAS WELL INTO A
YEAR BEFORE I COULD GRASP WHAT
REALLY HAPPENED.
THE GRIEF AND THE PAIN IS SO
TREMENDOUS.
IT'S SO -- IT'S IT LIKE YOUR
BREATH IS TAKEN AWAY.
YOUR HEART IS RACING.
YOU CAN'T BREATHE.
YOU CAN'T THINK.
AND SO SOMETIMES YOU ARE IN A
SURREAL SITUATION.
AND IT COMES AND GOES.
SOMETIMES IT'S REAL AND
SOMETIMES IT'S LIKE JUST A
LIVING NIGHTMARE.
AND YOU THINK YOU ARE GOING TO
WAKE UP THE NEXT DAY IT'S
GOING TO BE BETTER.
AND IT TAKES A LONG TIME.
I THINK FOR YOU TO UNDERSTAND
THE REALITY OF WHAT HAPPENED
AND REALLY BE ABLE TO DEAL
WITH THE REALITY, RATHER THAN
ALL OF THE SUPERFICIAL THAT'S
GOING ON RIGHT NOW.
>> Steve: RIGHT.
>> THERE IS SO MUCH.
THERE IS A LOT OF MEDIA.
THERE IS A LOT OF TALK.
AND IT TAKES A LONG TIME TO
FIGURE OUT WHAT WAS REAL AND
WHAT WASN'T.
SHE AND I WERE JUST IN THAT
PARTICULAR CASE YOU BLAME THE
YOUNG MAN WHO TOOK YOUR
DAUGHTER'S LIFE AND THE LIVES
OF SO MANY OTHER OUT THERE
THEY WERE EVIL INCARNATE ON
EARTH AND YOU WERE ANGRY FOR A
WHILE.
YOU ARE NOT ANGRY ANYMORE.
HOW LONG DID IT TAKE YOU TO
GET TO THAT STAGE?
IT TOOK QUITE A WHILE.
ONE OF THE THINGS THAT HELPED
WE WERE ABLE TO DO SOMETHING
ABOUT RACHEL'S WRITINGS AND
JOURNALS AND DRAWINGS THAT SHE
LEFT BEHIND AND THAT KIND OF
GAVE US A PLATFORM TO START
COOL PROGRAMS AND DO A LOT OF
SPEAKING TO LOOK AT THE GOOD
THAT COULD COME OUT OF IT THAT
WAS A VERY HEALING POINT.
AND ONCE WE SAW THAT, WE WERE
ABLE TO PUT THINGS IN A BETTER
PERSPECTIVE I DON'T BELIEVE IT
WAS RACHEL'S TIME TO DIE BUT
SHE DID.
AS A RESULT WE WERE ABLE TO
MOVE FORWARD AND TURN
SOMETHING EVIL INTO GOOD.
THAT BROUGHT A LOT OF HEALING.
THAT ALSO HELPED DEAL WITH THE
ANGER AND FRUSTRATION OF
LOSING HER.
BUT I STILL HAD TO DEAL WITH
CRAIG WHO WAS EXTREMELY
TRAUMATIZED.
SUFFERED FROM PTSD FOR A LONG
TIME.
AND MY CONCERN WAS I WOULD
HAVE TWO COLUMBINE VICTIMS.
ONE FROM THE SHOOTING AND ONE
FROM EMOTIONAL CRIPPLE.
>> Steve: SURE.
>> RELIVING DAY IN AND DAY OUT
WHAT HE EXPERIENCED.
IT TOOK HIM ALMOST TWO YEARS
BEFORE I SAW HIM TURN A CORNER
AND BECOME A REGULAR TEENAGER
AGAIN AND START
LIFE WHICH HE HAS DONE IN A
VERY POWERFUL WAY NOW.
>> Steve: YOU GIVE VERY
POWERFUL WITNESS TO WHAT
HAPPENED TO THE PARENTS THERE.
WE KNOW THAT YESTERDAY
REOPENED ALL OF THOSE BAD
MEMORIES OF COLUMBINE.
SO BETH WE THANK YOU VERY MUCH
FOR JOINING US TODAY TO SHARE
YOUR STORIES FROM COLORADO.
>> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
>> Steve: YOU BET:  ALL RIGHT,
STRAIGHT AHEAD, BRAND NEW
DETAILS ABOUT THE SHOOTER AND
HIS BROTHER WHO REPORTEDLY
HADN'T SPOKEN TO EACH OTHER IN
TWO YEARS.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
o as you cas
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
For thos...this...ions of doing
this...
...and this,
dancing in their heads...
...we have these.
Home Depot gift cards.
Give the gift of doing,
in-store or online.
>> Alisyn: WE ARE HAPPY YOU
ARE JOINING US THIS MORNING.
HEAVY HEARTS SITTING HERE AS
THE PRESIDENT SAID YESTERDAY
EVERY AMERICAN'S HEART IS
BROKEN.
WE DO HAVE NEW INFORMATION FOR
YOU THIS MORNING.
WE DO WANT TO BRING YOU ALL OF
THE LATEST.
WE ARE CONTINUING OF COURSE
OUR COVERAGE OF THIS TRAGEDY
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
HERE ARE SOME THE MOST HEART
WRENCHING SCENES IN THE
AFTERMATH OF THIS HORRENDOUS
CRIME.
>> EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY
TODAY.
>> A QUALITY CAME INTO
DISPATCH.
POLICE OFFICERS AND RESOURCES
FROM ALL OVER THE STATE RACED
TO THAT AREA AS THEY CONVERGED
ON THE SCHOOL.
THE CHILDREN OBVIOUSLY WERE
VERY SHAKEN.
THEY WERE CRYING IN THE
CLOSET.
WHEN THEY WERE LEAVING THE
POLICE MADE THEM HOLD HANS AND
TOLD THEM TO CLOSE THEIR EYES.
>> THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
GYM TEACHERS DIRECTED US TO
STAY AGAINST THE WALL AND
EVERYBODY STARTED TO KIND OF
PANICKING NO WORDS, SHEAR
TERROR.
>> IT DOES NOT SEEM REAL.
IT DOES NOT SEEM LIKE IT'S
EVEN POSSIBLE.
>> WE ALL HUDDLED AND I KEPT
HEARING THESE BOOMING NOISES.
[SIREN]
>> JUST ALL OF US MOMS
NETWORKING TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT WHAT'S GOING ON.
KIDS WERE TERRIFIED.
THEY HAD JUST WITNESSED
SOMETHING AND THEY WERE
TERRIFIED MOST TERRIFYING
THINGS I HAVE BEEN THROUGH.
>> IN THE WORDS OF SPRICHTER
HEAL THE BROKEN HEARTED AND
BIND UP THEIR WOUNDS.
>> Steve: ADAM LANZA AFTER HE
MURDERED HIS MOTHER AT THEIR
HOUSE DROVE HER CAR TO THE
SCHOOL SHE WORKED AT AND
MURDERED 20 CHILDREN AND SIX
ADULTS.
>> Brian: ARMED TO THE TEETH.
WE DO HAVE NEW INFORMATION FOR
YOU.
IF YOU READ THE "NEW YORK
TIMES" TODAY YOU PERHAPS HEARD
OR SAW THERE THAT THEY SAY THE
PRINCIPAL BUZZED IN THE WOULD
BE ASSASSIN.
>> Steve: BECAUSE OF A NEW
SECURITY SYSTEM THEY HAD
INSTALLED.
>> THAT'S JUST NOT TRUE AND
ABC IS REPORTING NOW AFTER
DOING INTERVIEW WITH THE
INVESTIGATOR IN CHARGE WHO
WILL HOLD A PRESS CONFERENCE
SHORTLY HE GOT IN BECAUSE HE
SMASHED HIS WAY IN THROUGH THE
GLASS AT THE FRONT OF THE
SCHOOL AND THEN STORMED
THROUGH THE HALL WHICH WOULD
EXPLAIN WHY THE PRINCIPAL AND
THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST HEARD
SOME COMMOTION, WENT TO THE
HALL AND PERHAPS WERE HIS
FIRST VICTIMS.
>> Steve: THE DOOR WAS LOCKED.
>> Alisyn: THIS IS ACCORDING
TO GEORGE CINCO OF THE NOWTOWN
POLICE DEPARTMENT.
IT MAKES MORE SENSE THAT THE
GUNMAN BROKE HIS WAY.
IN HE HE SMASHED THE WINDOW
ADJACENT TO THE DOOR HANDLE
AND WAS ABLE TO GAIN ACCESS
THAT WAY AND THAT DOES MAKE
MORE SENSE.
BUT LET'S TELL YOU ABOUT THE
STORIES.
THE TEACHERS THE HEROIC
TEACHERS HAD WHO KNEW WHAT TO
DO WHO KNOWS IF THEY EVER HAD
A DRILL OF THIS MAGNITUDE.
STILL JUST INSTINCTIVELY THEY
KNEW TO BARRICADE THE DOORS
AND TO HIDE THEIR KIDS.
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT THIS 3RD
GRADE TEACHER KATELYN ROIG
DID.
SHE ASSEMBLED ALL 14 OF HER
KIDS INTO A BATHROOM THAT WAS
CONNECTED TO THEIR CLASS AFTER
BARRICADING THE DOOR AND SHE
JUST SAT WITH THEM AND TOLD
THEM TO BE AS QUIET AS
POSSIBLE.
I PUT ONE OF MY STUDENTS ON
TOP OF THE TOILET.
I JEWS KNEW WE HAD TO GET IN
THERE.
I WAS TELLING THEM IT'S GOING
TO BE OKAY.
YOU ARE GOING TO BE ALL RIGHT.
I HAD PULLED THE BOOK SHELF
BEFORE I CLOSED THE DOOR IN
FRONT OF IT SO IT WAS
COMPLETELY -- WE WERE
COMPLETELY BARRICADED IN.
>> DID YOU TELL THEM TO BE
QUIET?
>> OH, YEAH.
>> DID YOU WORRY ABOUT --
>> -- I TOLD THEM TO BE QUIET.
I TOLD THEM WE HAD TO BE
ABSOLUTELY QUIET.
I WAS JUST SO AFRAID THAT IF
HE DID COME IN AND HE WOULD
HEAR US AND HE WOULD MAYBE
START SHOOTING THE DOOR I SAID
NO, WE HAVE TO BE ABSOLUTELY
QUIET I SAID THERE ARE BAD
GUYS OUT THERE NOW.
WE NEED TO WAIT FOR THE GOOD
GUYS.
I JUST WANTED US TO BE OKAY.
AND I'M SO, SO SADDENED THAT
THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO, IN THIS
SITUATION, ARE NOT OKAY.
MY HEART GOES OUT TO ANYONE
WHO KNEW THEM ALGD AND PASS
PART OF THEIR LIVES I CAN'T
IMAGINE.
>> SHE HAD 14 KIDS INSIDE THAT
RESTROOM.
SHE SAT THERE, ANY KID QUIET
HOLD HIS FACE OR HER FACE
QUIET DOWN EVERYTHING IS GOING
TO BE OKAY OTHER STORIES MARY
ROSE BARRICADED HER KIDS IN A
CLASSROOM.
THEY HID IN A CLOSET THEY
STAYED THERE.
THE GUNMAN BANGED ON THE DOOR
SAYING LET ME IN.
SHE DID NOT.
SHE WOULDN'T TALK ABOUT HER
ACTION, HERO.
CAN'T I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU
ACTED THAT WAY.
I DON'T WANT TO TALK ABOUT IT
I WANT TO TALK ABOUT WHERE WE
GO FROM HERE AND HOW WE HELP
THESE FAMILIES.
>> THAT 3RD GRADE TEACHER
LITTLE BIT MORE TO THE STORY
POLICE FOUND THEM POLICE, I
DON'T BELIEVE YOU.
YOU NEED TO PUT YOUR SLIDE
YOUR IDS UNDER.
SHE THOUGHT IT WOULD BE THE
GUNMAN.
OBVIOUSLY THEY WERE TRAUMA
MIZE MA ADVERTISED.
IF YOU WERE THE POLICE YOU
WOULD HAVE A KEY TO THE
BATHROOM SHE MADE THEM GO AND
GET THE KEY AND COME BACK.
>> Steve: HE WAS THE POLICEMAN
ANSWERED CAME TO SAVE THE DAY.
MEANWHILE THE FBI JUST CLEARED
THE SUSPECT'S FAMILY,
INCLUDING HIS BROTHER AND HIS
OLDER BROTHER AND FATHER, HIS
OLDER BROTHER RYAN WAS
INITIALLY MS. ESTABLISH AS
ADAM THE GUNMAN.
ANNA COIN MAN JOINS US NOW
FROM HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY, WHAT
DO WE KNOW ABOUT THE LANZA
FAMILY?
GOOD MORNING TO EVERYBODY AT
HOME.
WE ARE STANDING IN FRONT OF
THE APARTMENT BUILDING OF THE
BROTHER OF THE SHOOTER,
24-YEAR-OLD RYAN LANZA.
HE APPARENTLY LIVES HERE WITH
TWO OTHER PEOPLE NOW
EVERYTHING WE ARE HEARING IS
THAT THE BROTHER HAD
ABSOLUTELY NOTHING TO DO WITH
IT AND IS NOT A SUSPECT.
ALTHOUGH HIS HOME, HIS
COMPUTER, HIS PHONE RECORDS
ALL BEING SEARCHED.
A RELIABLE SOURCE AND THE FBI
TELLING US HE WAS VERY
COOPERATIVE WITH THEM AND
MENTIONED HE HAD NOT EVEN
SPOKEN TO HIS BROTHER ADAM
SINCE 2010 HE SAID HIS BROTHER
HAD PERSONALITY DISORDER AND
POSSIBLY AUTISM AS WELL.
CONFUSION OVER THE IDENTITY OF
THE SHOOTER.
HE SAID IT WASN'T ME.
I WAS AT WORK.
NOW, THAT CONFUSION OVER THE
IDENTITY MAY HAVE STEMMED
BECAUSE ADAM WAS CARRYING THE
I.D. OF RYAN.
YESTERDAY, HOBOKEN POLICE AND
THE FBI ON SCENE.
ALSO NEIGHBORS HERE IN THE
NEIGHBORING APARTMENT BUILDING
SAYS THAT THE BOMB SQUAD WAS
RUNNING THROUGH THEIR
HALLWAYS.
>> STILL, IN THE BACK OF YOUR
HEAD, WHAT COULD POSSIBLY HAVE
HAPPENED, YOU KNOW, THERE IS
HUNDREDS AND HUNDREDS OF
THINGS.
YOU KNOW, YOU ARE JUST STILL
SHOCKED.
>> YOU CAN'T HELP IT YOU KNOW,
HUG YOUR OWN CHILDREN, YOU
KNOW, A LITTLE MORE AT NIGHT
WHEN YOU PICK THEM UP.
AWFUL STORY.
>> AWFUL STORY.
>> THE FBI SAYS THAT THE
BROTHER AND FATHER HAD BEEN
CLEARED AND NO LONGER ARE
BEING QUESTIONED BY
AUTHORITIES.
AND THEY MAY POSSIBLY BE IN
CONNECTICUT.
THAT'S WHERE THE FATHER LIVES
IN STANFORD.
HE HAS REMARRIED AFTER
DIVORCING THE MOTHER, NANCY,
WHO WAS, OF COURSE, KILLED IN
THE RAMPAGE YESTERDAY AS WELL.
BUT AUTHORITIES ARE STILL
TRYING TO PIECE ALL OF THIS
TOGETHER AND WE'LL BRING YOU
THE LATEST AS THE STORY
DEVELOPS.
BACK TO YOU.
>> Steve: ALL RIGHT, ANNA,
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
ALSO THEY ARE TRYING TO PIECE
TOGETHER THE IMAGES OF THE
SHOOTER.
I MEAN, IT'S VERY COMPLICATED.
FOR INSTANCE, THE "NEW YORK
TIMES" SAYS SMART,
INTROVERTED, NERVOUS.
DAILY NEWS SAYS DARKED AND
DISTURBED, TROUBLED BOY FROM A
WEALTHY FAMILY.
A TICKING TIME BOMB AS WELL.
ONE OF THE NEWSPAPERS
DESCRIBES HIM AS A REAL GAMER.
SOMEBODY WHO LOVED VIDEO GAMES
AND THINGS LIKE THAT.
AND I THINK SOMEBODY IS GOING
TO HAVE TO LOOK INTO THAT
BECAUSE WHEN YOU LOOK AT THE
ACCURACY, WITH WHICH HE WAS
ABLE TO SHOOT THE PEOPLE IN
THAT SCHOOL, THERE IS A REPORT
OUT THIS MORNING THAT HE ONLY
WOUNDED ONE PERSON.
EVERYBODY ELSE HE SHOT DEAD.
COULD THAT BE RELATED DON'T
KNOW.
>> Brian: STRAIGHT AHEAD, YOUR
CHILD DIDN'T NEED TO BE AT THE
SCENE OF THE SHOOTING TO BE
TRAUMATIZED.
JUST HEARING ABOUT IT COULD BE
TRAUMATIC.
AS A PARENT, WHAT DO YOU DO?
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN IT?
THAT'S NEXT.
[SIREN]
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU LIKE WHO YOU ARE...
AND YOU LEARNED SOMETHING
ALONG THE WAY.
THIS IS THE AGE OF KNOWING
WHAT YOU'RE MADE OF.
SO, WHY LET
ERECTILE DYSFUNCTION
GET IN YOUR WAY?
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT VIAGRA.
20 MILLION MEN ALREADY HAVE.
ASK IF YOUR HEART
IS HEALTHY ENOUGH FOR SEX.
DO NOT TAKE VIAGRA IF YOU TAKE
NITRATES FOR CHEST PAIN;
IT MAY CAUSE AN UNSAFE DROP
IN BLOOD PRESSURE.
SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE
HEADACHE, FLUSHING,
UPSET STOMACH,
AND ABNORMAL VISION.
TO AVOID LONG-TERM INJURY,
SEEK IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
FOR AN ERECTION
LASTING MORE THAN FOUR HOURS.
STOP TAKING VIAGRA
AND CALL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU EXPERIENCE
A SUDDEN DECREASE OR LOSS
IN VISION OR HEARING.
THIS IS THE AGE
OF TAKING ACTION.
VIAGRA.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR.
SEE IF AMERICA'S
MOST PRESCRIBED ED TREATMENT
IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
I NEED YOU.
I FEEL SO ALONE.
BUT YOU'RE NOT
ALONE.
I KNEW YOU'D COME.
LIKE I COULD STAY AWAY.
YOU KNOW I CAN'T DO THIS
WITHOUT YOU.
YOU'LL NEVER HAVE TO.
YOU'RE ALWAYS THERE
FOR ME.
SHH!
I'LL GET YOU
A RENTAL CAR.
I COULD ALSO USE
AN UMBRELLA.
FALL IN LOVE WITH
PROGRESSIVE'S CLAIMS SERVICE.
YOU WON'T TAKE OUR FUTURE.
AIDS AFFECTS US ALL.
EVEN BABIES.
CHEVRON IS WORKING TO STOP
MOTHER-TO-CHILD TRANSMISSION.
OUR EMPLOYEES AND THEIR FAMILIES
ARE PART OF THE FIGHT.
AND WE'RE WINNING.
AT CHEVRON NIGERIA, WE HAVEN'T
HAD A REPORTED CASE IN 12EARS.
AIDS IS STRONG.
BUT WE ARE STRONGER.
AND AIDS...
♪
AIDS IS GOING TO LOSE.
>> Alisyn: THIS MORNING WE ARE
TALKING ABOUT SECURITY AND GUN
CONTROL THAT'S THE NATIONAL
DIALOGUE.
ONE THING PEOPLE ARE NOT
TALKING ABOUT HOW TO CHANGE
THE CULTURE.
DR. JEFF GARDEIR IS HERE TO
TALK TO US BEFORE WE GET TO
TALK ABOUT HOW CULTURE IS
PLAYING A ROLE IN THIS.
THE BROTHER SAYS THE SHOOTER
HAS A PERSONALITY DISORDER.
HELP US UNDERSTAND THAT WHAT
IS HE TALKING ABOUT WHEN HE
SAYS A PERSONALITY DISORDER?
>> WELL, HE MAY BE TALKING
ABOUT SOMETHING WE CALL A
SKITS ZIP CODE OR A SKITS OWE
TYPE PERSONALITY DISORDER.
WHAT WE KNOW ABOUT THESE
PARTICULAR DISORDERS, PEOPLE
ISOLATE THEMSELVES, THEY HAVE
A BIT OF A DIFFERENT REALITY.
THEY DON'T HAVE MANY SOCIAL OR
INTERACTIONAL SKILLS.
>> Brian: SEEMS WENT THROUGH
HIGH SCHOOL.
>> FROM WHAT WE HEAR AND THEY
HAVE THEIR OWN REALITY.
WE ARE NOT SAYING THAT THEY
ARE SCHIZOPHRENIC.
THEY DON'T HAVE HALLUCINATIONS
BUT THEY CERTAINLY LIVE IN A
DIFFERENT WORLD THAN OURS.
>> OUR WORLD HAS CHANGED OVER
THE LAST 20, 30 YEARS.
THE CULTURE HAS CHANGED.
I WAS TALKING A LITTLE BIT
ABOUT APPARENTLY THIS GUY WAS
AN EXPERT GAMER.
>> YEAH.
>> Steve: MAYBE THE RATING
SYSTEM NEEDS TO BE CHANGED
WITH REGARD TO VIDEO GAMES.
HE SEEMS TO HAVE BEEN DEADLY
ACCURATE.
>> HE MIGHT HAVE LEARNED HOW
TO DO THAT ON THOSE GAMING
SYSTEMS.
AND THAT MAY HAVE LED INTO AND
SUPPORTED A LOT OF THE
DELUSIONAL THINKING.
THIS WAS A VERY DISTURBED
INDIVIDUAL.
DELUSIONAL THINKING THAT HE
MAY HAVE HAD.
IN SOME WAYS I THINK WE ALL
HAVE TO TAKE RESPONSIBILITY,
PERHAPS NOT LETTING OUR KIDS
PLAY A LOT OF THOSE GAMES,
ESPECIALLY IF THEY HAVE SOME
EMOTIONAL ISSUES.
THOSE ARE THE ONES THAT WE
KEEP AWAY FROM THOSE VIOLENT
GAMES.
>> Brian: HE HAS GOT NO
FRIENDS.
HE IS PAINFULLY SHY.
DOESN'T WANT TO INTERACT YET
HE HAS THIS GENIUS SIDE TO
HIM.
PEOPLE CALL HIM EVIL GENIUS OR
VERY BRIGHT.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING TO GO
THESE GAMES WHERE YOU LOSE
YOURSELF.
HOW DO YOU STOP IT?
>> VERY DIFFICULT TO STOP IT.
IT COMES BACK TO THE
RESPONSIBILITY.
BUT HERE'S THE BANE OF THE
EXISTENCE OF MANY PARENTS.
IF THE KIDS HAVE SOME OF THESE
VERY SEVERE EMOTIONAL
DISORDERS AS THOSE KIDS GET
OLDER THEY BECOME A LOT MORE
UNCONTROLLABLE.
AND IT REALLY IS ABOUT GETTING
THEM, PERHAPS, TO STAY ON
MEDICATION OR TO BE DIAGNOSED.
SO IT'S IT'S DIFFICULT FOR THE
KIDS.
IT'S DIFFICULT FOR THE PARENTS
AND WE NEED TO STEP UP OUR
MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEM TO ASSIST
THOSE PARENTS IN CONTROLLING
AND WORKING.
>> Alisyn: SOMEBODY DOESN'T
WANT TO TAKE THEIR MEDICATION,
HOW ARE YOU SUPPOSED TO DO
THAT?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, THERE IS
INVOLUNTARY MEDICATION, BUT,
AGAIN, YOU HAVE TO RESPECT THE
RIGHTS OF THE PATIENTS AND
JUST BECAUSE SOMEONE MAY HAVE
A SCHIZOPHRENIA OR PERHAPS A
PERSONALITY DISORDER WHICH WE
REALLY DON'T MEDICATE, YOU
CAN'T REALLY FORCE THEM
BECAUSE YOU HAVE TO RESPECT
THEIR RIGHTS.
THAT'S THE CONUNDRUM.
THAT'S WHERE WE ARE REALLY ALL
STUCK.
>> Steve: IT IS TOUGH.
WE DON'T HAVE A GOOD IMAGE OF
WHAT WAS GOING ON IN THAT
HOUSE UP IN NEWTOWN IN THAT
CONNECTICUT.
YOU ARE TALKING ABOUT THE
CULTURE HAS HARDENED PERHAPS
IT NEEDS TO CHANGE TO A
SIMPLER, MORE WHOLESOME TIME
PATIENTS NEED TO DO THEIR JOB.
THEY NEED TO PARENT.
>> AS MUCH AS THEY CAN.
THEY NEED TO REACH OUT TO
OTHER PARENTS, ESPECIALLY WHEN
IT BECOMES DIFFICULT FOR THEM.
>> Brian: I JUST THINK THIS
GUYS IS NUTS.
LIKE THE GUY IN AURORA.
TO ME THAT ISN'T HANDS ON
PARENTING.
I DON'T KNOW IF ANY PARENT CAN
REIGN IN THAT TYPE OF MENTAL
CONDITION.
>> THAT IS THE MAJOR ISSUE,
LOOK.
PEOPLE DO HAVE MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES, IT DOESN'T MEAN THAT
THEY BECOME VIOLENT.
WE HAVE TO BE ABLE TO WORK
WITH THEM TO BE COMPLIANT ON
THEIR MEDICATIONS TO BE ABLE
TO GO TO THE THERAPY.
IT'S DIFFICULT THE WAY THE
MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEM IS SET UP
RIGHT NOW, IT JUST DOES NOT
REACH OUT TO ENOUGH PEOPLE.
AND AS A PSYCHOLOGIST.
I HAVE TO STEP UP MY GAME AND
HELP PARENTS IN DEALING WITH
THESE VERY DIFFICULT
SITUATIONS.
>> THIS WHAT S. WHAT WE ALL
NEED TO DOES A SOCIETY.
>> Steve: VERY DIFFICULT
SITUATION.
>> I WILL BE SEEING YOU AGAIN.
>> Alisyn: EXPECTING TO LEARN
A LOT MORE IN A FEW MINUTES
BECAUSE THERE IS A PRESS
CONFERENCE ABOUT TO GET
UNDERWAY.
WE WILL BRING IT TO YOU LIVE.
>> Brian: EVERY ONE OF THE
PRESS CONFERENCES HAS BEEN
LATE.
WE WILL STAY WITH IT AND MAKE
THE ADJUST.
S.
>> Steve: FORENSICS CAN TELL
YOU A LOT ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
WITH LANZA.
FORENSIC PATHOLOGIST
DR. MICHAEL BADEN COMING UP
NEXT.
>> THE SCHOOL IS IN LOCKDOWN.
I WILL
instructions ?
Shouldn't something
that's truly advanced,
not need much explanation
at all ?
With the Nokia Lumia 822
on Verizon,
there's not much to learn
because it's
powered by Windows...
to let you do more than you ever
imagined on your smartphone.
Exclusively with Data Sense--
a feature that makes
the most of your plan.
Only on Verizon.
BECAUSE  HELPS YOU KEEP DOING
WHAT YOU LOVE.
NO WONDER IT'S AMERICA'S
#1 SELLING PAIN RELIEVER.
YOU TOOK ACTION,
YOU TOOK ADVIL®.
AND WE THANK YOU.
>> Alisyn: BACK WITH
CONTINUING COVERAGE OF THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
OUR NEXT GUEST CONNECT THE
DOTS.
HERE TO BRAKE IT DOWN IS
DR. MICHAEL BADEN.
NICE TO HAVE YOU HERE WITH US.
WE HAVE BREAKING NEWS RIGHT
NOW.
THAT IS AT THIS HOUR THE
VICTIMS' BODIES, SOME OF THEM,
ARE BEING REMOVED FROM THE
SCHOOL.
WHAT TOOK SO LONG?
IT'S ALMOST BEEN 24 HOURS.
>> THEY HAD TO DO LIKE 26
SEPARATE HOMICIDES, DOCUMENT
THE BODIES, IDENTIFY THEM AS
BEST THEY COULD.
MAKE CHARTS AND TAKE LOTS OF
PHOTOGRAPHS OF WHERE THE
BODIES ARE.
BECAUSE THIS MAY BE IMPORTANT
LATER ON IN UNDERSTANDING WHAT
HAPPENED.
>> Alisyn: I KNOW THIS IS YOUR
LIVELIHOOD AND SO I HESITATE
TO SOMEHOW DENIGRATE IT BUT WE
KNOW WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
THERE WON'T BE A TRIAL.
THERE IS NO TRIAL.
WHY PUT THE PARENTS THROUGH
ALL OF THESE FORENSICS?
>> TWO THINGS, NUMBER ONE,
THERE WON'T BE A TRIAL ON THE
ADAM.
THERE IS GOING TO BE A LOT OF
CIVIL TRIALS ON THIS.
THERE WILL BE CIVIL TRIALS
ABOUT THE SCHOOL, ABOUT
MEDICATION, ABOUT SECURITY.
AND THERE MAY BE A POLICE
INVESTIGATION IF THERE IS
ANOTHER PERSON WHO HELPED ADAM
DO THIS BECAUSE, REMEMBER,
THIS TOOK A WHILE TO GET
TOGETHER FOR HIM TO DO.
THERE MAY BE A CRIMINAL CHARGE
AGAINST SOMEBODY.
SO THE POLICE WANT TO GET
EVERYTHING RIGHT.
NOW, FORTUNATELY, THEY HAVE AN
EXCELLENT FORENSIC PATHOLOGIST
IN CHARGE IN THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT WANE CARVER.
HE WILL DO EVERYTHING HE CAN
TO GET THE BABIES BACK TO THE
FAMILIES AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
BUT NOT ONLY DO THE
PHOTOGRAPHS ON IDENTIFICATION
HAVE TO BE DONE RIGHT.
X-RAYS, SEE IF THERE IS ANY
BULLS IN THE BODIES.
BULLETS IN THE BODIES.
>> Alisyn: YOU HAVE TO DO THAT
AGAIN, I HATE THE IDEA OF
PUTTING THE PARENTS THROUGH
ANY MORTAR TEMPERATURE YOU
MUST DO THAT BECAUSE THAT WILL
TELL YOU IF HE HAD HELP
SOMEHOW OR IF THIS WAS AN ACT
ALONE.
>> IT WILL TELL IF YOU THERE
IS A FOURTH GUN INVOLVED.
THE BULLET THAT THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER LEAVES BEHIND IS THE
BULLET THAT MAY HAVE COME FROM
ANOTHER GUN.
SO IT IF THEY HAVE BULLETS
FROM SAY THREE GUNS THAT ADAM
HAD, MAYBE THERE IS A 40
BULLET FROM ANOTHER GUN THERE
WAS A QUESTION IN THE
BEGINNING AS TO WHETHER THERE
WAS A FOURTH SHOOTER.
>> A SECOND SHOOTER.
>> EXCUSE ME A SECOND SHOOTER
A YEAR OR TWO FROM NOW WHEN
THIS MAY COME TO COURT THOSE
ISSUES WILL BE RAISED AGAIN.
>> Alisyn: YOU MAKE A GREAT
POINT.
WHEN WILL THE PARENTS BE ABLE
TO GET THEIR LOVED ONES?
>> I WILL SUSPECT THEY WILL
START GETTING THEM FROM THE
MEDICAL EXAMINERS BECAUSE THE
FARMINGTON, MEDICAL EXAMINER'S
OFFICE HOPEFULLY BY SUNDAY,
MONDAY, TUESDAY.
THERE WILL BE BODIES STILL
THERE MONDAY.
ALSO THEY HAVE GOT TO DO A
THOROUGH EXAMINATION OF THE
SHOOTER.
NOT ONLY THE CAUSE OF DEATH.
WHAT DRUGS WAS HE ON?
A DRUG OF ABUSE?
HAD HE SEEN A PSYCHIATRIST AND
WAS HE ON ANY THERAPEUTIC
DRUGS.
>> Alisyn: TOXICOLOGY REPORTS
FOR THE SHOOTER IS VERY
IMPORTANT.
>> VERY IMPORTANT.
>> Alisyn: THERE IS A PRESS
CONFERENCE EXPECTED AT ANY
MOMENT AND WE WILL BRING IT TO
YOU AS SOON AS IT HAPPENS.
STUDENT, WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
>>  GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE, WE
ARE AWAITING A LIVE PRESS
CONFERENCE OUT OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT WHERE WE EXPECT TO
LEARN NEW DETAILS ABOUT THE
VICTIMS OF THIS HORRIBLE
TRAGEDY AND ABOUT THE SHOOTER
WHO TOOK THE LIVES OF 26
PEOPLE, INCLUDING 20 CHILDREN.
>> Brian: WE WILL GO TO THAT
PRESSER AS SOON AS IT STARTS
AND YOU CAN TOTALLY UNDERSTAND
IT, BUT EVERYBODY HAS BEEN
RUNNING BEHIND AND LAST NIGHT
EVERY PRESS CONFERENCE RAN
BEHIND AND VERY BRIEF AND THE
FACTS WERE SKETCHY WHICH
REALLY EXPLAINS WHY IF YOU GO
TO THE HARTFORD CURRENT OR THE
LOCAL PATCH PAPER AND TALK TO
GO A REPORTER AND TALK TO THE
NEW YORK TIMES OR THE NEW YORK
POST OR DAILY NEWS, A LOT OF
THE FACTS ARE STILL FLUID, SO
TO SPEAK, AND A LOT OF THINGS
THAT MATTER A LOT ARE STILL
UNCLEAR.
THAT'S WHY THIS PRESS
CONFERENCE, I IMAGINE, WILL
CLEAR A LOT UP.
>> Steve: I HOPE SO, WE'RE 23
HOURS AFTER ONE OF THE WORST
MASS MURDERS IN AMERICAN
HISTORY AND THE SHOOTING AT
VIRGINIA TECH WHERE 32 DIED.
IT'S TOO EARLY.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO KNOW WHAT
THE MOTIVE IS.
WE DON'T KNOW WHY 20-YEAR-OLD
ADAM LANZA MURDERED HIS MOM
AND DROVE HIS CAR TO THE WHERE
SHE WORKED.
AND THERE'S ONE OTHER THING
ABOUT YESTERDAY, I HAVEN'T
HEARD ANYBODY TALK ABOUT AND
YOU KIND OF TOUCHED ON IT A
LITTLE BIT, ALI.
YESTERDAY, SCHOOL PRAYER
RETURNED TO SANDY HOOK BECAUSE
A NUMBER OF REEFERS HEARD THE
COMMOTION AND LOCKED THEIR
KIDS IN CLOSETS AND CORNERS,
WHAT ELSE DID THEY DO, THEY
PRAYED.
>> Alisyn: AND WHAT ELSE CAN
YOU DO.
AND NEW PICTURE EMERGES FROM
ADDS DAM LANZA, HE WAS 20
YEARS OLD.
PARENTS DIVORCED IN 2008 OR
2009 AND LIVED WITH HIS MOM
WHO HE LATER KILLED IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, GUNS
FOUND AT THE SCENE WERE
REGISTERED TO HIS MOM, THERE
WERE THREE GUNS AND BROTHER
RYAN DESCRIBED HIS BROTHER AS
BASICALLY A COMPUTER NERD, A
TECHNO GEEK.
OTHER PEOPLE DESCRIBED HIM AS
REMOTE.
THE BROTHER ALSO SAID THAT HE
THOUGHT HIS BROTHER MIGHT HAVE
HAD ASPERGER'S SYNDROME AND A
PERSONALITY DISORDER.
>> Brian: AS WE DID FIND OUT
AND ASPERGER'S BARELY IS THERE
VIOLENCE ASSOCIATED WITH IT,
BUT YOU DON'T KNOW SOME TYPE
OF ADVERSE MEDICATION.
IF THEY ARE HIS MOM'S GUNS AND
ONE OF THE GUNS, ONE OF THE
WEAPONS WAS TO BE IN THE CAR,
THANKFULLY NOT USED WAS A
RIFLE THEY SAY IS USED FOR BIG
GAME HUNTING.
I QUESTION HOW EXTE--
HE WENT TO THE CLASSROOMS,
HARTFORD CURRENT, THERE WERE
TWO DIFFERENT CLASSROOMS,
WE'VE HEARD DIFFERING REPORTS
WAS THE MOM A TEACHER, AN
AIDE, DID SHE STEP ASIDE TO
TRY TO SOLVE SOME OF HER SON'S
PROBLEMS AT 20 YEARS OLD.
>> Steve: WE DID HEAR THE
LIEUTENANT EARLIER ON ANOTHER
CHANNEL, I'M SURE WE'LL HEAR
MORE.
THE NEW YORK TIMES IS
REPORTING THAT THEY STALLED
THIS NEW SECURITY SYSTEM AT
THE SCHOOL WHEN SOMEBODY CAME
TO THE DOOR, ONLY ONE DOOR TO
ENTER AFTER SCHOOL STARTED
9:30.
AND WE LEARNED THAT THE KID
DIDN'T BUZZ THE DOOR, HE
BUSTED THE GLASS AND CAME IN,
THERE WAS A STORY THAT THE
PRINCIPAL HAD BUZZED HIM IN.
THAT APPARENTLY IS NOT TRUE.
THE PRINCIPAL WAS IN A THREE
ON ONE MEETING, THE PRINCIPAL,
THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST AND A
VICE PRINCIPAL TALKING TO A
PARENT ABOUT ONE OF THE
CHILDREN AND HEARD COMMOTION
AND THE PRINCIPAL WENT OUT,
REALIZED THIS KID WAS SHOOTING
AT PEOPLE, TOLD SOME OF THE
PEOPLE TO BACK UP.
YELLED LOCK YOUR DOORS AND SHE
WAS DEAD WITHIN TEN SECONDS.
>> Brian: HOW ABOUT THE
CURRENT OF A PRINCIPAL WALKING
TO A GUNMAN, RATHER THAN
RUNNING AWAY, CONFRONTING,
CONFRONTING ALONG WITH THE
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST AND 56
YEARS OLD AND ACCORDING TO
FAMILY MEMBER SET TO RETIRE AT
THE END OF THE YEAR, THEY BOTH
LOSE THEIR LIVES AND VICE
PRINCIPAL TWO WOUNDS, TRYING
TO RECOVER WITH THE ARM AND
LEGS.
AND THE ADMINISTRATION WAS
DOING THE BEST TO BLOCK AND
PROTECT.
>> Alisyn: THERE ARE WONDERFUL
THINGS COMING OUT ABOUT THE
PRINCIPAL, HOW DEDICATED TO
HER STUDENTS AND HOW MUCH SHE
LOVED HER CAREER PATH AND A
VERY ACTIVE TWITTER FEED AND
SHE WOULD TWEET OUT MESSAGES
ALL THE TIME AND ON THE
OPENING DAY THIS YEAR,
SEPTEMBER THE FIRST DAY OF
SCHOOL, I'M SO EXCITED TO
WELCOME IN THE KINDERGARTENERS
AND HOPE STOKE THEIR LIFE LONG
LOVE OF LEARNING AND A COUPLE
OF THINGS ABOUT THE SHOOTER AS
WELL.
HE REPORTEDLY WAS AN HONOR
STUDENT AND LOCAL JOUNLISTS
DUG UP HONOR ROLLS, HE WAS AT
LEAST IN ELEMENTARY AND HIGH
SCHOOL AND PERHAPS A
PERSONALITY DISORDER SET IN.
NO CRIMINAL HISTORY.
WHEN SOMETHING LIKE THIS
HAPPENS, EVERYONE LOOKS FOR
WHAT WERE THE WARNING SIGNS
HOW COULD WE HAVE EVER STOPPED
THIS.
IF YOU DON'T HAVE ANY VIOLENT
BEHAVIOR BEFORE THAT AND
YOU'RE JUST A STRANGE, REMOTE
COMPUTER GEEK, WHAT ARE YOU --
HOW CAN YOU EVER STOP IT?
NEIGHBORS DESCRIBED HIM AS A
LITTLE ODD AND PERHAPS A
COMPULSIVE--
>> THEY WANT TO CONNECT THE
DOTS AND WE SHOULD HAVE
REALIZED WHEN HE DID THIS.
LOOK, SOMETHING HAPPENED.
HE WAS EVIL YESTERDAY AND HE
KILLED A WHOLE BUNCH OF
PEOPLE.
>> Brian: AND THE DAILY NEWS
QUOTES A CLASSMATE OF HIS, A
NEIGHBOR OF HIS, I CAN'T SAY I
COULDN'
HAPPENING, BUT ROT IN HELL.
NEIGHBORS WERE TOTALLY FREAKED
OUT BY THIS GUY.
>> Steve: I SAW THAT SAME
QUOTATION, BUT THERE ARE A LOT
OF ROTTEN PEOPLE WHO ARE NOT
EVIL INCARNATE AND WHO DO NOT
COMMIT MURDER.
AND A SCHOOL CUSTODIAN, HEARD
GUNSHOTS AND RAN UP AND DOWN
THE HALLS AND ALERTED
TEACHERS, LOCK YOUR DOORS.
THERE WAS A SCHOOL NURSE WHO
HEARD THE COMMOTION AND HER
INCLINATION WAS TO RUN INTO
THE HALL TO FIGURE OUT WHAT'S
GOING ON, BUT INSTEAD SHE
REMEMBERED THE PROTOCOL THEY
TALKED ABOUT WHEN THEY WERE IN
A LOCKDOWN AS THEY WERE
APPARENTLY YESTERDAY AND HID
UNDER THE DESK AND THE DESK,
SHE LOOKED UNDER THE, YOU
KNOW, THE SKIRT OF THE DESK
AND SHE SAW THE GUNMAN'S FEET.
HE WAS RIGHT AT HER DESK.
SHE REMAINED COMPLETELY QUIET
AND HE TOOK OFF AND STARTED
SHOOTING AGAIN.
>> Brian: LET'S TALK ABOUT THE
MUSIC TEACHER.
>> Alisyn: LET'S DO THAT.
OBVIOUSLY IT'S THE CHRISTMAS
SEASON AND JUST THE NIGHT
BEFORE THIS TRAGEDY, THE MUSIC
TEACHER AT THIS SCHOOL SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY, MARY ROSE LED
HER STUDENTS IN A HOLIDAY
CONCERT.
I WISH, I THINK, I DON'T KNOW
IF WE HAVE IT RIGHT NOW.
THERE'S SOUND FOR THAT AND
SPECIAL THAT IS AND LET'S
WATCH THAT FOR ONE SECOND.
.
>> MY MUSIC TEACHER TOLD US TO
GET INTO THE CLOSET.
AND AT FIRST I THOUGHT IT WAS
JUST A PRACTICE, BUT THEN I
REALIZED THAT EVERYTHING WAS
REAL AND WE WERE ALL IN THE
CLOSET AND WE WERE SAYING A
PRAYER.
>> Alisyn: SO THAT'S THAT
STUDENT RESPOND TO GO WHAT THE
TEACHER DID.
THE TEACHER WAS ALSO--
HAD HER WITS ABOUT HER AND PUT
THEM IN THE CLOSET EVEN AS THE
GUNMAN WAS APPARENTLY POUNDING
ON THE DOOR AND SAYING LET ME
IN.
>> Brian: A SCARY THING.
>> Steve: SO SHE LOCKED THE
DOOR FROM THE INZOO I HAD
WHIHAD--
FROM THE INSIDE WHICH WAS THE
KEY.
AND THE GUNMAN WAS KNOCKING ON
THE DOOR SAYING LET ME IN.
>> Brian: YOU WANT TO HEAR
SOME OF THE CONCERT.
THIS IS BEFORE IT TOOK PLACE,
BACK THE NIGHT BEFORE.
OH, WE DON'T?
OKAY, I THOUGHT WE DID, MY
FAULT.
SO, HEARD THE STUDENT IN THE
CLASS TALK ABOUT THAT.
WHEN THEY WENT UP TO THE MUSIC
TEACHER AND HEARD THE ACCOUNT
OF WHAT YOU DID.
SHE SAYS I DON'T WANT TO TALK
ABOUT WHAT I DID, I WANT TO
TALK ABOUT THE HEALTH OF THE
FAMILIES OF THOSE WHO LOST
THEIR LIVES AND KIDS WHAT
THEY'VE GONE THROUGH.
>> Alisyn: THERE'S SOMETHING
ABOUT THAT BOY, THAT
PARTICULAR LITTLE BOY WHO WE
HEARD JUST SPEAK THAT'S
PARTICULARLY POIGNANT.
AND I THINK YOU FORGET HOW
LITTLE THOSE BOYS ARE UNTIL
YOU HEAR THEIR VOICES.
AND THAT BOY'S VOICE AS HE'S
ABLE TO RECOUNT THAT TERROR IN
HIS LITTLE BOY VOICE AND THERE
WERE KINDERGARTEN,IN THIS
CLASS WHO HAD TO DEAL WITH
THIS, THIS TERROR AND ALL OF
THESE KIDS IN THE SCHOOL, AS
THE PRESIDENT SAID YESTERDAY,
THESE WERE LITTLE BEAUTIFUL
KIDS FROM FIVE TO TEN YEARS
OLD AND YOU SPOKE TO THE MOM
FROM COLUMBINE WHO ALSO IS SO
PROFOUND IN EVERYTHING SHE
SAYS AND SO POIGNANT AND TALKS
ABOUT HOW THIS WILL BE WITH
THEM, LIKE HER SON, FOR LIFE,
BUT HOPEFULLY THEY WILL GET
THE HELP THAT THEY NEED TO
MOVE ON FROM THIS.
>> Steve: RIGHT.
WHAT SHE SAID WAS AFTERWARDS
SHE WAS OBVIOUSLY DAZED AND
ANGRY AT KLEBOLD AND HARRIS.
AND SHE REGARDED THAT AS EVIL
ON EARTH AND BLAMED THEM AND
TOOK A WHILE AND EVENTUALLY
CAME TO--
TO RECOGNIZE HER DAUGHTER WAS
GONE, HER SON HAD WITNESSED
IT.
HE WAS SUFFERING FROM
TRAUMATIC STRESS SYNDROME,
STILL DOES.
BUT YOU KNOW, SHE SAYS THAT
THESE PARENTS OF THESE
CHILDREN WHO WERE KILLED
YESTERDAY, IT'S GOING TO BE A
LONG ROAD FOR THEM AND THEY'RE
THE NOT GOING TO KNOW WHAT HIT
THEM FOR A VERY LONG TIME.
>> Brian: AND WE UNDERSTAND
ACCORDING TO THE HARTFORD
CURRENT, TWO CLASSROOMS, AND
WE'VE HEARD REPORTS
KINDERGARTEN CLASSROOMS AND
HOPEFULLY GET IT CLEARED UP
TODAY.
ONE OF THE FIRST GRADE
TEACHERS HEARD THE SHOOTING
AND HAD TO SPRING INTO ACTION.
WHAT WOULD KAITLIN HOYT DO
WHEN SHE HAD THE KIDS IN THE
CLASSROOM AND HEARD THE
SHOOTING.
AND DIDN'T KNOW THIS WAS
HAPPENING, BUT IN THAT GRADE.
THERE WAS A BATHROOM IN THE
ACTUAL CLASSROOM AND ASKED ALL
HER KIDS TO GET IN THERE.
SO CROWDED THEY HAD TO STAND
ON TOP OF THE TOILETS AND SOME
OF THEM WOULD MAKE NOISE AND
SOME WOULD SIT THERE IN HORROR
AND SOME THOUGHT IT WAS A GAME
AND SHE KNEW IT WAS ESSENTIAL
THEY STAY QUIET AND HERE IS
THAT TEACHER TALKING ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED YESTERDAY AT
1Y9D 30 IN THE MORNING.
>> I PUT ONE OF MY STUDENTS ON
TOP OF THE TOILETS.
I KNEW WE HAD TO GET IN THERE
AND TELLING THEM IT'S GOING TO
BE OKAY, YOU'RE GOING TO BE
ALL RIGHT.
AND I PULLED THE BOOK SHELF
BEFORE I CLOSED THE DOOR IN
FRONT OF IT SO WE WERE
COMPLETELY BARRICADED IN.
>> DID YOU TELL THEM TO BE
QUIET.
>> YEAH.
>> DID YOU WORRY--
>> I TOLD THEM TO BE QUIET.
WE HAD TO BE ABSOLUTELY QUIET
I WAS AFRAID IF HE DID COME IN
AND HEAR US HE WOULD MAYBE
START SHOOTING THE DOOR, NO,
WE HAVE TO BE ABSOLUTELY QUIET
AND I SAID WE'RE WAITING FOR
THE GOOD GUYS AND I JUST, I
WANTED US TO BE OKAY SO
SADDENED THAT THERE WERE
PEOPLE IN THE SITUATION WHO
ARE NOT OKAY.
AND MY HEART, MY HEART GOES
OUT TO ANYONE WHO, PART OF
THEIR LIVES.
>> Alisyn: THE MOST HEART
WRENCHING THING ABOUT WHAT SHE
SAYS THERE, AT LEAST I'M
READING IT IN THE TRANSCRIPT
OF WHAT HE SHE SAID, WE DIDN'T
PLAY IS THERE.
SHE WOULD TAKE THEIR HEAD,
THEIR FACE INS HER HANDS AND
TELL THEM IT'S GOING TO BE
OKAY, IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY,
SHE WANTED THAT TO BE THE LAST
THING THEY HEARD.
>> Brian: THAT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
FROM PAST RECORDS YOU KNOW HOW
THE GRADES AND CLOSE, FIRST
GRADE, SECOND GRADES, THIRD
GRADES, AND CURRICULUMS AND
TWO FIRST GRADE CHARMS THAT
WERE MASSACRED AND SHE'S
SITTING THERE AND GOT TO LIVE
WITH WHAT, WHO IS LEFT AND THE
HORROR THAT SHE'S BEEN THROUGH
AND SHE DEFINES TRAUMATIZED.
>> Steve: THERE IS ONE OTHER
COMPONENT AND WE DON'T KNOW
THE BACK STORY BECAUSE
SOMEBODY IN THE OFFICE AS THE
COMMOTION STARTED YESTERDAY.
PUSHED DOWN THE BUTTON ON THE
PUBLIC ADDRESS SYSTEM WHERE
THEY DO THE FLAG SALUTE AND
SOMEBODY PUSHED IT DOWN AND
THE ENTIRE BUILDING HEARD AT
LEAST ONE PERSON SCREAMING AND
IT'S UNCLEAR WHETHER THERE
WERE GUNSHOTS WERE AUDIBLE OR
NOT AND CREDITING WHOEVER DID
THAT WITH PERHAPS SAVING LIVES
BECAUSE AS SOON AS PEOPLE
HEARD THAT, THE TEACHERS AND
OTHER STAFF MEMBERS, THEY LOCK
THE DOORS FROM THE INSIDE.
AND PERHAPS, YOU KNOW, YOU
LISTEN TO THE STORY ABOUT THE
MUSIC TEACHER AND THE GUY IS
BANGING ON THE DOOR, OPEN UP,
THE GUY WITH THE THE GUN, HOW
MANY LIVES WERE SAVED BECAUSE
SOMEBODY PUSHED A BUTTON FOR
TWO SECONDS.
>> Brian: RIGHT WEEKS' WAITING
FOR THE PRESS CONFERENCE,
COULD START ANY SECOND AND
WE'LL GO RIGHT TO IT AND WE'LL
LEAVE THE SCREEN AND YOU'LL
TAKE IN THAT, YOU'LL SEE THE
OFFICER SITTING BEHIND THE
MICROPHONE AND GETTING THE
LATEST AND LET'S CONTINUE TO
SPECULATE FROM AN EDUCATION
A-PERSPECTIVE.
ROD WHEELER A HOMICIDE
DETECTIVE.
SEES SADLY A LOT OF THESE
CRIME SCENES AND NOTHING, I
WOULD ARGUE, AS SAD AS
CHILDREN LOSING THEIR LIVES AT
SCHOOL.
AND WHAT HAS YOUR SCRATCHING
YOUR HEAD?
>> I THINK THE MAIN THING
WE'RE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT,
BRIAN, TALKING ALL MORNING
TOLD.
WHAT COULD HAVE BEEN THE
MOTIVE AND WHAT WAS THE SPARK?
AS I INDICATED EARLIER THAT
IGNITED THIS GUY YESTERDAY.
THERE HAD TO BE SOMETHING AND
SO THAT'S WHAT THE POLICE ARE
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT.
THAT'S WHAT WE ALL WANT TO
KNOW AND THE OTHER VERY
IMPORTANT QUESTION HERE, WHERE
DID HE GET THIS AMMUNITION
FROM?
AND I KEEP GOING BACK TO THAT
FOR A REASON.
REASON I'M GOING BACK TO THAT
HE DIDN'T GET THAT AMMUNITION
YESTERDAY MORNING, HE HAD TO
HAVE ACCUMULATED THAT OVER A
PERIOD OF TIME.
SO, AS A RESULT OF THAT, THE
QUESTION BECOMES, WAS THIS AS
PLANNED EVENT AND WHETHER OR
NOT ANYBODY WAS INVOLVED WITH
THEM.
AND THAT'S STILL SOMETHING
THAT THE POLICE ARE TRYING TO
FIGURE OUT RIGHT NOW, BRIAN.
>> Brian: LET'S THINK ABOUT
THAT.
WE KNOW HE HAD PROTECTIVE
EQUIPMENT WHETHER IT WAS A
BULLET-PROOF VEST.
AND EXCUSE ME?
>> AND CALMO, TOO.
>> I THOUGHT IT WAS A BLACK
OUTFIT, THOUGH, TOO, BUT HE
HAD HOLLOWED OUT BULLETS, BUT
I'M NOT A BALLISTICS EXPERT,
BUT I UNDERSTAND FLOWER AFTER
IMPACT INSIDE THE BODY.
>> THOSE ARE THE WORST BULLETS
YOU CAN HAVE.
THEY'RE HOLLOW POINT AND THE
KIND WE IN LAW ENFORCEMENT
HATE, THEY CAN PENETRATE A
BULLET-PROOF VEST.
WHERE DID HE GET THAT
AMMUNITION FROM?
WAS ANYBODY INVOLVED WITH THIS
GUY?
OBVIOUSLY THIS WAS A PLANNED
EVERETT AND SET OUT, I THINK,
PROBABLY, DAYS AGO TO COMMIT
THIS ACT.
>> Alisyn: I HAVE A QUESTION.
I WANT TO TALK ABOUT NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT FOR A SECOND AND
LET PEOPLE KNOW WHAT IT'S
LIKE.
IT'S THIS VERY PRECIOUS, VERY
SWEET, I'VE SPENT TIME THERE,
A BEAUTIFUL TOWN WITH LOVELY
TOWN SQUARES AND BEAUTIFUL OLD
CHURCHES ADORNING DIFFERENT
CORNERS AND SMALL,
PARTICULARLY HAMLET OF SANDY
HOOK.
IS THIS SOMETHING, SOMETHING
AS HIDEOUS AS THIS CRIME THAT
A SMALL LITTLE TOWN POLICE
DEPARTMENT LIKE THE NEWTOWN
POLICE OFFICERS, WOULD THEY
EVER HAVE HAD A DRILL TO TRAIN
FOR A SCHOOL SHOOTING?
>> YOU KNOW, THAT'S AN
EXCELLENT QUESTION AND I CAN
TELL YOU THE ANSWER IS YES.
WHY?
BECAUSE IF YOU LOOK
HISTORICALLY, ALISYN, AT A LOT
OF THESE TYPE OF SHOOTINGS,
THEY HOPE IN REMOTE AREAS, YOU
KNOW, WE DON'T HAVE A WHOLE
LOT OF MASS SHOOTINGSES IN THE
INNER CITY AREA THAT YOU EVER
NOTICE THAT.
A LOT OF TIMES THEY HAPPEN IN
REMOTE AREAS.
LOOK AT COLUMBINE, ALL POLICE
DEPARTMENTS ACROSS THIS
COUNTRY REALLY, AS A RESULT OF
COLUMBINE AND OF COURSE,
VIRGINIA TECH, ALISYN, WE'VE
BEEN PRACTICING ON THIS AND
CONTINUE TO PRACTICE ON THIS
ON A REGULAR BASIS, EVERY
POLICE DEPARTMENT.
NOW WHY?
BECAUSE THESE SITUATIONS CAN
HAPPEN AT ANY TIME AND THAT'S
WHY IT'S EQUALLY IMPORTANT FOR
ALL OF OUR VIEWERS TO
UNDERSTAND THAT YOU HAVE TO
HAVE A PLAN IN PLACE NOW,
ALISYN, IN CASE SOMETHING LIKE
THIS HAPPENS.
LET'S HOPE IT NEVER HAPPENS
AGAIN, BUT THE TIME TO PLAN
HOW YOU'RE GOING TO RESPOND TO
THIS IS NOW.
>> AS A DETECTIVE AND YOU TRY
TO PUT THIS CRIME SCENE
TOGETHER, PEOPLE SAY CRIMES OF
PASSION, LOOK FOR THIS.
CRIMES OF HATE, STRANGERS,
WHATEVER.
WHAT ABOUT THE FACT THAT HE
SHOOTS HIS MOM AND GOES TO
WHAT WE BELIEVE WAS HER WORK
PLACE.
SOMETHING ABOUT THAT WORK
PLACE COULD SYMBOLIZE
SOMETHING THAT HE WANTED TO
RECTIFY, TAKE HER OUT AND THEN
TAKE OUT SOMETHING ELSE THAT
SHE LOVED.
>> THAT SHE LOVED OR WAS
COMING BETWEEN HER AND HIM AND
HIS MOM.
>> RIGHT.
AND THERE HAD TO BE SOMETHING,
AS I INDICATED EARLIER, BRIAN,
AND I DON'T LIKE TO SPECULATE,
AS YOU GUYS KNOW, TOOUCH IN
THESE CASES.
IT'S VERY EARLY IN THIS CASE,
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT I HONESTLY
BELIEVE?
I THINK THERE HAD TO BE
SOMETHING GOING ON BETWEEN
THIS GUY'S MOTHER AND THE
SCHOOL AND TOOK HIS MOTHER OUT
FIGURED IN HIS MIND HE'S GOING
TO GET EVEN WITH THAT SCHOOL,
THAT PRINCIPAL, AGAIN, DON'T
WANT TO SPECULATE HERE, THAT
DOESN'T DO ANYBODY ANY GOOD,
BUT HOWEVER, WE HAVE AN
OBLIGATION TO TRY TO PUT THE
PIECES TOGETHER TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT WAS IT TO CAUSE THIS GUY
TO SELECT THOSE CLASSROOMS.
ONE OF THE ACTUAL WITNESSES
SAID WHEN THIS GUY CAME INTO
THE SCHOOL HE SPECIFICALLY
WENT TO A CERTAIN CLASSROOM.
WHY DID HE DO THAT?
WHY DIDN'T HE JUST START
SHOOTING IN THE HALLWAY?
WE DON'T KNOW.
THAT'S ANOTHER IMPORTANT
QUESTION WE'RE TRYING TO
FIGURE OUT HOW, BRIAN.
>> ROD WHEELER, THANKS.
AND STAY CLOSE, WE'LL WAIT FOR
THE PRESS CONFERENCE AND THE
FACTS THIS MORNING.
>> Alisyn: THANKS, MEANWHILE
WE WANT TO BRING IN MIKE
HUCKABEE, GOVERNOR, 1998,
JONESBORO, ARKANSAS.
>> YEAH.
>> Alisyn: THERE WAS A SCHOOL
SHOOTING, AGAIN, YOUNG MEN,
YOUNG BOYS.
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
>> I MEAN, I REMEMBER VIVIDLY,
I'LL NEVER FORGET IT, MARCH
24TH, 1998 AND WHAT WAS
TRAGIC, A 11-YEAR-OLD AND A
12-YEAR-OLD, WHO AMBUSHED
THEIR FELLOW STUDENTS AND
TEACHERS, KILLING FIVE,
WOUNDING TEN OTHERS, IT WAS A
HORRIBLE SCENE.
THE WORST OF IT WAS THAT NO
ONE REALLY EVER PREPARED FOR A
11-YEAR-OLD COMMITTING MASS
MURDER.
A 11-YEAR-OLD, NOT ENOUGH TO
GO EVEN THROUGH PUBERTY, SO
THERE WERE NO LAWS IN PLACE
THAT SAID YOU CAN KEEP THIS
KID FOREVER, YOU ADJUDICATE
HIM WHEN HE'S A JUVENILE AND
HAVE TO LET HIM GO WHEN HE'S
18.
THERE ARE THINGS ABOUT THE
CRIMINAL JUSTICE SYSTEM THAT
SAYS THIS, AND PEOPLE SAY YOU
SHOULD HAVE A LAW AND THERE IS
ONE THOU SHALLT NOT KILL.
>> Brian: THEY'RE NEVER
TALKING ABOUT THE CULTURE.
>> Steve: WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
OUR CULTURE AND OUR CULTURE
HAS HARDENED.
>> AND WE HAVE TO LOOK AT THAT
IN AN HONEST WAY AND DON'T
MEAN TO BE SIMPLISTIC AND
YESTERDAY ON CAVUTO, HE ASKED
WHERE WAS GOD.
WE'VE REMOVED THEM.
AND SOME SAID IF WE HAVE
PRAYER IN SCHOOLS THIS
WOULDN'T HAVE HAPPENED.
MY POINT IS A LARGER POINT,
THAT WE HAVE AS A CULTURE
DECIDED THAT WE DON'T WANT TO
HAVE VALUES, THAT WE DON'T
WANT TO SAY THAT SOME THINGS
ARE ALWAYS RIGHT AND SOME
THINGS ARE ALWAYS WRONG.
WHEN WE DIVORCE OURSELVES FROM
A BASIC SENSE OF WHAT WE WOULD
CALL, I WOULD SAY, COLLECTIVE
MORALITY WHERE WE AGREE ON
CERTAIN PRINCIPLES TO BE TRUE
ALWAYS, THEN WE CREATE A
CULTURE, NOT THAT IT
SPECIFICALLY CREATES THIS
CRIME.
IT DOESN'T, BUT IT CREATES AN
ATMOSPHERE IN WHICH EVIL AND
VIOLENCE ARE REMOVED FROM OUR
SENSE OF RESPONSIBILITY.
THE GOVERNOR YESTERDAY SAID
TEVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY.
AND HE SPOKE AS A DAD AND NOT
AS A POLITICIAN, YOU COULD SEE
THE EMOTION, HE QUOTED
SCRIPTURE, WE ALWAYS GO BACK
TO THE CULTURAL NORMS IN THE
MOMENTS OF CRISIS AND ACT LIKE
WE'RE ASHAMED TESTIFY THE REST
OF THE YEAR.
>> Brian: THE SCHOOL HAD IT IT
RIGHT AND THE GOVERNMENT HAD
IT WRONG.
THAT SCHOOL SEEMED TO BE A
HOME RUN IN EVERY WAY AS AN
EDUCATIONAL FOUNDER AND THE
PRINCIPAL DRESSING UP, FUNNY
FACES AND GREETING CHILDREN.
MY PRINCIPAL NEVER SAID THREE
WORDS.
>> THERE WERE TIMES WE WISHED
OUR PRINCIPAL WOULD HAVE
DRESSED UP.
THAT'S A GREAT POINT, BRIAN.
AN EXEMPLARY SCHOOL AND SOME
WOULD SAY A IDYLLIC COMMUNITY.
AND WE ALWAYS SAY THIS IS THE
LAST PLACE IT WOULD HAPPEN,
NO, IT'S REALLY NOT BECAUSE IT
CAN HAPPEN ANYWHERE, ANYTIME
AND THAT'S WHY WE CAN PASS A
THOUSAND THOUSANDS AND
ANYTHING CAN HAPPEN IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY, IT CAN AND IT
UNFORTUNATELY WILL HAPPEN.
>> Alisyn: BUT TO BRIAN'S
POINT.
YOU TALK ABOUT THE CULTURE
SOMEHOW GOING AWRY, BUT I
THINK THAT WHEN YOU LOOK AT
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT THIS IS A
TOWN OF -- YOU SEE THE PARENTS
RUNNING TO THE SCHOOL.
THESE ARE GOOD PARENTS, AND
THIS IS BEAUTIFUL CULTURE AND
THESE ARE PEOPLE WHO ARE STILL
CONNECT TODAY THEIR COMMUNITY,
BE IT A CHURCH, BE IT A
SYNAGOGUE.
SO, SOMETHING MUST BE GOING
WRONG WITH YOUNG MEN.
I MEAN, IT'S YOUNG MEN WHO
PERPETRATE ALL OF THESE SCHOOL
SHOOTING AND SADLY THEY ARE
HE' ON THE RISE.
THERE'S SOMETHING, I DON'T
KNOW A SENSE OF ILLNESS?
I DON'T KNOW HOW WE DIG DEEP
TOWER GET TO THE ANSWER, BUT
YOU CAN'T SAY IT'S THAT
CULTURE, LOOK AT THAT
BEAUTIFUL CULTURE.
>> IT'S NOT THE CULTURE OF
NEWTOWN, IT'S THE GENERAL
CULTURE OF OUR SOCIETY.
AN EXAMPLE, WHEN I WAS IN
SCHOOL IT WAS NORMAL THAT WE
CARRY GUNS TO SCHOOL, OKAY?
IN OUR CARS AND PICKUP TRUCKS,
GUNS WERE IN OUR, BECAUSE WE
HUNTED BEFORE SCHOOL, WE
HUNTED AFTER.
LISTEN, IT NEVER OCCURRED--
>> COULD HAVE GUN RACKS IN OUR
TRUCKS.
>> AND STAYED IN THE SCHOOL
PARKING LOT.
IT NEVER OCCURRED TO ANY OF US
THAT WE WOULD EVER USE THAT
GUN TO KILL OUR CLASSMATES.
THE CULTURE POINT I'M TALKING
ABOUT, WE UNDERSTOOD WHAT GUNS
WERE, WE UNDERSTOOD WE WEREN'T
TO USE THEM ON EACH OTHER.
TODAY, YOU HAVE KIDS WHO USE
GUNS IN GAMES, THEY HAVE A
DISCONNECT FROM REALITY.
THE GUNS THEY SEE AND HEAR ARE
NOT REAL AND THEY SOMEHOW
DON'T UNDERSTAND THAT THERE
ARE REAL CONSEQUENCES.
>> GO AHEAD.
>> I WAS JUST GOING TO SAY
THIS PARTICULAR SHOOTER WHO
SHOT ALL THE PEOPLE WERE
APPARENTLY AN EXPERT GAMER,
AND NEW YORK TIMES THEY TALKED
A LITTLE ABOUT THAT.
YOU MENTIONED A SCHOOL PRAYER,
IT RETURNED YESTERDAY.
>> YEAH.
>> Steve: A BUNCH OF STORIES
OF TEACHERS WHO MASSED THEIR
KIDS IN CLOSETS AND CORNERS
AND WHAT DO THEY DO, WAIT FOR
THE POLICE.
>> AND PRAY.
>> Brian: GOVERNOR, AND BRING
IN SOMETHING ELSE, THOUSAND
SHALL NOT KILL AND WORK A
JACKHAMMER DURING A TALK SHOW
IN THE BACKGROUND.
>> Alisyn: I DON'T KNOW IF THE
VIEWERS CAN HEAR IT, IT'S
DEAFENING.
>> LIKE A DENTIST IN THE
MAKEUP ROOM.
>> Brian: BRINGING BACK BAD
MEMORIES.
GOVERNOR, KEEP IN MIND, TOO,
YOU KNOW THIS, EVEN THOUGH
THERE'S THE GABBY GIFFORDS
HORROR AND AT AURORA HORROR
AND IN THE MALL.
THERE ARE A LOT OF PEOPLE
WALKING IN AND AROUND SHOPPING
IN MALLS, NOTHING IS IT
HAPPENING AND SCHOOLS ARE
OPENING AND CLOSING, NOTHING
IS HAPPENING, THERE'S NO
THREAT.
SECURITY IS WORKING FINE.
WE OBVIOUSLY HIGHLIGHT
SOMETHING THAT'S THE SECOND
WORSE MASSACRE IN THE HISTORY
OF THE COUNTRY WHEN IT COMES
TO SCHOOLS, BUT I ALSO THINK
THAT THE PEOPLE AT HOME ARE
WRITING AND SAYING THIS, I
DON'T WANT EVERYONE TO GO TO
SCHOOL TOMORROW, ON MONDAY AND
THINK TO THEMSELVES ARE WE
GOING TO GET SHOT TODAY, IT'S
NOT REALITY.
>> NO, IT'S NOT REALITY.
AND JUST LIKE PLANE CRASHES
AND PEOPLE SAY I'M GOING TO
CANCEL MY NIGHT.
OR A BUS ACCIDENT, OR TRAINS,
IT'S A NATURAL HUMAN RESPONSE
WE WANT TO SURVIVE AND SO WE
LOOK AT ALL FORMS OF THREAT
AND WE TRY TO ELIMINATE
BUT WHAT HAPPENED YESTERDAY IS
THE KIND OF OUT OF THE BLUE,
THAT'S WHY WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
IT, WHY WE'VE GONE 24/7
TALKLING ABOUT IT, BECAUSE
IT'S UNUSUAL.
THE DAY IT'S NORMAL, OR
ROUTINE, ONE OF THE DOZENS
STORIES COVERED IN THE HALF
HOUR.
IT'S NOT SO MUCH THAT WE
SHOULD BE SHOCKED WHEN THIS
HAPPENED, WHEN I SAY SHOCKED,
YES, IT SHOULD--
THE DAY IT BECOMES ROUTINE AND
DON'T ALL FEEL A GUT-PUNCH,
THAT'S WHEN WE NEED TO WORRY.
>> Alisyn: IF HISTORY HAD GONE
DIFFERENTLY AND IF YOU WERE
PRESIDENT TODAY, WHAT WOULD
YOU HAVE THE NATIONAL DIALOG
BE TOMORROW ABOUT THIS?
>> I THINK YOU WOULD GRIEVE.
THIS IS NOT A TIME TO HAVE A
DIALOG ABOUT WHAT TO DO AND I
THINK THE BIG MISTAKE TODAY
WOULD BE TO HAVE ALL OF THESE
POLITICAL OR PHILOSOPHICAL
DISCUSSIONS HOW DO WE PREVENT
IT BECAUSE IT'S NOT THE TIME.
THE TIME NOW IS TO GRIEVE,
IT'S TO TO PUT OUR ARMS AROUND
THIS COMMUNITY AND THESE
FAMILIES AND KIDS WHO SAW
SOMETHING THEY'LL NEVER EVER
GET BEYOND AND TO DO
EVERYTHING WE CAN TO GRIEVE.
AND THERE'S A TIME FOR ALL OF
THAT, IT'S NOT TODAY AND NOT
THIS WEEKEND.
>> ARE YOU GOING TO BE LIVE
THIS WEEKEND?
>> WE'LL BE LIVE TONIGHT TO DO
A SPECIAL SHOW AND WE'LL HAVE
DARRYL SCOTT, WHO IS THE
FATHER OF RACHEL SCOTT FROM
COLUMBINE, AND MAX WILL BE
WITH US AND TALK ABOUT HOW DO
YOU TALK TO YOUR FAMILY,
PARTICULARLY TO LITTLE KIDS
AND EXPLAIN THE GRIEF PROCESS
TO THEM WHO MAYBE HAVE NEVER
BEEN THROUGH IT BEFORE.
>> GOOD MORNING AB WE'LL LET
YOU PREPARE FOR YOUR SHOW.
>> THANK YOU, STEVE, ALISYN--
>> AS YOU LOOK THERE, HAD A
LIVE IMAGE OUT OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT WHERE WE WERE TOLD
THAT THE PRESS CONFERENCE WITH
THE AUTHORITIES, INCLUDING THE
STATE POLICE, LOCAL POLICE WAS
GOING TO START AT EIGHT
O'CLOCK.
KEEP IN MIND, INSIDE THAT
SCHOOL, IT'S A GIGANTIC CRIME
SCENE WHERE 26 HOMICIDES TOOK
PLACE YESTERDAY.
DR. MICHAEL BODDEN, ESTEEMED
FORENSIC PSYCHOLOGIST JOINS US
LIVE NOW HERE.
WHAT HAVE THEY BEEN DOING
OVERNIGHT IN THE SCHOOL.
>> OVERNIGHT THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER HAS BEEN LOOKING AT
THE BODIES AND WORKING WITH
THE CSI, THE CRIME SCENE
POLICE, DOCUMENTING WHERE EACH
BODY IS, DOCUMENTS FOR THE
SHELL CASINGS.
>> WHY IS THAT IMPORTANT?
>> WE KNOW WHO DID IT AND WE
KNOW HE CAME IN AND HE JUST
STARTED SHOOTING.
>> RIGHT, BECAUSE TO DOCUMENT
EVERYTHING IS IMPORTANT FOR
FUTURE PUBLIC HEALTH HOLLIES
DISCUSSIONS AND ALSO, THE
FUTURES AND JUST BECAUSE THERE
ARE NO CRIMINAL LAWSUITS
DOESN'T MEAN A LOT OF CIVIL
LAWSUITS WHERE ALL OF THIS IS
IT GOING TO BE IMPORTANT WHERE
THERE'S ANY DEFICIT IN THE WAY
THE CHILDREN WERE HANDLED,
THEY HAVE TO PHOTOGRAPH THE
SCENE, DIAGRAM THE SCENE, BUT
THEN, AND THAT'S BEEN GOING ON
24 HOURS.
NOW, THE BODIES WOULD NORMALLY
HAVE TO GO TO FARMINGTON WHERE
THE CONNECTICUT MEDICAL
EXAMINER IS AND X-RAYS TAKEN
AND THE INDIVIDUAL GUNSHOT
WOUNDS WILL BE DOCUMENTED.
NOW, IN THE X-RAYS, IF THERE
ARE BULLETS IN THE BODIES
BECAUSE SOME OF THE BODIES
WENT THROUGH, THERE'S AN ISSUE
OF AUTOPSIES HAVING TO BE DONE
TO DOCUMENT EACH BULLET WITH
EACH GUN.
>> Alisyn: AND WHAT DO PARENTS
SAY, AND I JUST WANT THE BODY
OF MY CHILD RETURNED TO ME.
>> THE WISHES, THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER'S DETERMINATION.
>> Alisyn: BECAUSE IT'S A
CRIME SCENE, PARENTS DON'T
HAVE THE CHOICE.
>> THE PARENTS HAVE A CHOICE
TO TELL THE MEDICAL EXAMINER
WHAT THEIR OPINION IS.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER MASS TO
SEE WHAT THE RESPONSIBILITY IS
AND NORMALLY, THE PARENT
DOESN'T WANT THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER TO DO THE AUTOPSY
THEY CAN GO TO COURT AND GET A
COURT ORDER, BUT THAT TAKES
DAYS AND DAYS AND THE FAMILIES
WANT REMAINS BECAUSE OF BURIAL
ARRANGEMENTS AND GRIEVING AND
THAT'S THE TENSION IN THE NEXT
COUPLE OF DAYS.
>> AND HOW IS THE
COMMUNICATION FOR THE MOST
PART IN A SITUATION LIKE THIS,
YOU HAVE A BE JOB TO DO, GUYS
LIKE YOU, TO GET THE PARENTS
THAT WANT TO KNOW DETAILS
ABOUT THEIR CHILD.
AND HOW IS--
WAYNE CARVER THE CHIEF MEDICAL
EXAMINER HAS BEEN AROUND A
LONG TIME AND ONE OF THE
IMPORTANT THINGS TO DO IS TO
GO TO THE--
PERIODICALLY TO GO TO THE
FIREHOUSE AND TELL THE PARENTS
WHAT PROGRESS IS BEING MADE
AND ALL THE THINGS THAT YOU
RAISED, AND GIVE ANSWERS TO
THE PARENTS SO THEY'RE NOT
LEFT OUT.
THAT THIS WAS A PROBLEM OF
FLIGHT 800 AND WHEN THEY WERE,
ALL THE PARENTS WERE--
MENTS A LOT OF ANGER.
>> AND STILL A THE LOT OF
ANGER, BECAUSE THEY WEREN'T
KEPT UP-TO-DATE.
AND HERE I'M SURE SOMEBODY
FROM THE MEDICAL EXAMINER'S
OFFICE AND SOMEBODY FROM THE
POLICE DEPARTMENT, GOING
PERIODICALLY EVERY HOUR, TWO
HOURS, TELLING THE FAMILIES
WHAT'S GOING ON AND WHAT'S
HAPPENING.
AND SO THAT THEY DON'T GET IT
FROM TELEVISION, THEY SHOULD
GET IT BEFORE IT GOES ON THE
TUBE.
>> WELL, OUR CORRESPONDENT UP
THERE REPORTED THE STORY THAT
APPARENTLY THEY HAVE SET UP A
MAKESHIFT MORGUE INSIDE THE
SCHOOL AND THEY'VE TAKEN
PICTURES OF THE CHILDREN.
>> RIGHT.
>> AND THEN IS IT STANDARD
THEN TO HAVE THE PARENT
IDENTIFY THEIR CHILD FROM A
PHOTOGRAPH?
>> YES, THEY HAVE TO MAKE, THE
EASIEST WAY TO IDENTIFY THE
CHILDREN WOULD BE MY
PHOTOGRAPHS, RATHER THAN
SEEING THE BODIES.
>> THEY DIDN'T WANT THE
PARENTS TO COME INTO THE
SCHOOL.
>> RIGHT, RIGHT, SO THEY CAN
DO IT BY PHOTOGRAPHS OR BY
VIDEO AND THEN THE PARENT WILL
HAVE A CHANCE TO SEE THEIR
CHILDREN AT THE FUNERAL HOME
AFTER EVERYTHING IS--
THE BLOOD--
>> DON'T GO TO THE CRIME
SCENE.
>> IT'S STILL A CRIME SCENE.
>> Brian: DR. BODDEN IN
EVERYTHING YOU'VE SEEN, IS IT
POSSIBLE, CAN YOU EVEN MAKE
SENSE OF A KILLER WHO CAN BE
AS HEARTLESS TO ASSASSINATE
CHILDREN AT POINT BLANK RANGE?
DO YOU UNDERSTAND THAT
MINDSET.
>> LET ME TELL YOU 50 YEARS OF
EXPERIENCE OF DOING THIS
STUFF.
EVERY MASS MURDER IS
DIFFERENT.
THIS ARE DIFFERENT BASES, I'VE
NEVER BEEN IN A SITUATION
WHERE CHILDREN WERE SELECTED
TO BE KILLED LIKE THIS AND
THIS WHOLE IDEA THAT HE HAD
SOMETHING WITH HIS MOTHER THAT
CAUSED HIM TO KILL HIS MOTHER
AND THEN KILLS ALL OF THE
CHILDREN, PRESUMABLY THAT SHE
MAY HAVE DONE SOME TEACHING
WITH.
SO, YEAH, I CAN'T UNDERSTAND
IT, BUT YOU CAN'T--
>> AND HAS NEVER KILLED
BEFORE, NEVER BEEN IN TROUBLE,
EVIDENTLY.
>> EXCEPT HE WAS KIND OF A
LONER AND FELT LEFT OUT AND HE
WASN'T A JOINER.
>> Alisyn: IS THAT A
UNIVERSAL?
>> THAT OFTEN HAPPENS WITH
THESE KIDS.
THEY'RE NOT JOINERS AND WANT
TO GET EVEN AND SHOW
EVERYTHING THAT THEY'RE
SUPERMEN AND IT'S ALSO
INTERESTING THAT POLICE HAVE
HAVE TO FIND OUT HOW MUCH OF
THE WEAPONS AND THE AMMUNITION
WAS IN THE HOUSEHOLD, YOU
KNOW, THAT HE COULD USE, BUT
CERTAINLY, HE HAD TO PREPARE
BY GETTING THE BULLET-PROOF
VEST AND THE CAMOUFLAGE
CHOATING.
AND THIS IS' STILL SOME THINGS
OUT THERE.
REMEMBER, THEY FOUND ANOTHER
PERSON IN THE WOODS WITH
CAMOUFLAGE IN THE BEGINNING.
>> Brian: YES.
>> AS YOU SAID EARLIER, EACH
NEWSPAPER IS GIVING A LITTLE
DIFFERENT STORY WHAT HAPPENED
AND PRESUMABLY THIS--
>> ONE OF THE MOST FASCINATED
THINGS HAPPENED.
WE SEE DR. BODDEN AND OTHER
EXPERTS AS THEY LEAVE OUR SET
TO GO GREEN ROOM AND YOU GUYS
ARE TRYING TO PIECE THIS
TOGETHER, TOO, BECAUSE THERE'S
A LOT OF ANSWERS NOBODY HAS.
>> I THINK WE'RE GOING TO GET
A LOT OF INFORMATION FROM THIS
PRESS CONFERENCE, HOPEFULLY.
>> THEY HAVE HE' BEEN VERY
RESPONSIBLE AND THEY, YOU
KNOW, IT SOUNDS LIKE AS SOON
AS IT'S RELIABLE INFORMATION,
THEY HAVE SHARED IT WITH US.
>> IT'S RELIABLE BECAUSE THEY
WANT EVERYBODY PROPERLY
IDENTIFIED AND--
>> WONDER WHAT THE DELAYS ARE,
THE DELAY COULD SHOW THEY'RE
FINDING OUT NEW INFORMATION.
>> IT WAS INTERESTING LAST
NIGHT WHEN THE SERGEANT VANCE,
THE TROOPER.
>> STATE POLICE.
>> THE STATE POLICE, HE WAS
SOLID AND HE WAS AT EIGHT
O'CLOCK AND HE MEANT EIGHT
O'CLOCK SO THERE'S SOMETHING
GOING ON RIGHT NOW TO MAKE A
DELAY.
>> RIGHT AND SOME OF THE
REPORTERS WERE ASKING SOME
QUESTIONS, NOW WHAT?
I'M NOT GOING TO GO INTO THAT
RIGHT NOW.
>> HE WAS VERY GOOD IN THE
FACT THAT DEFLECTING CERTAIN
QUESTIONS AND SAYING, HEY,
LOOK, WE'RE NOT UP TO THAT,
YET.
>> Alisyn: THANKS SO MUCH FOR
STICKING AROUND WITH US AND
CALL UPON YOUR EXPERTISE,
AGAIN WE'RE WAITING FOR THE
PRESS CONFERENCE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT YOU CAN SEE ALL
THE REPORTERS AND
PHOTOGRAPHERS THERE ASSEMBLED
AND SUPPOSED TO START A HALF
HOUR AGO, BUT WE ARE JUST
GOING TO KEEP AN EYE ON IT AND
WE'RE GOING TO HOPE THIS DELAY
MEANS THEY HAVE NEW
INFORMATION OF POSSIBLY ABOUT
THE SHOOTER, POSSIBLY ABOUT
WHAT IS HAPPENING WITH THE
VICTIMS AND THE ONGOING
INVESTIGATION.
>> AND JOINING US--
>> LET'S GO AHEAD AND TALK A
LITTLE BIT ABOUT THE PRINCIPAL
AT THE SCHOOL, A 47-YEAR-OLD
EDUCATOR BY THE NAME OF DAWN,
AND SHE HAD BEEN AT THE SCHOOL
A COUPLE OF YEARS AND BY ALL
ACCOUNTS A FANTASTIC PRINCIPAL
AND ABSOLUTELY LOVED HER JOB.
SHE WAS SADLY MURDERED
YESTERDAY, SHE WAS IN A
MEETING WITH ONE OF THE
PARENTS.
>> AND THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST.
>> Steve: AND THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST AND THE VICE
PRINCIPAL AND HEARD THE
COMMOTION OUTSIDE AFTER
APPARENTLY THE BROKE THROUGH
THE GLASS AND THERE SHE IS
RIGHT THERE.
SHE HAD THE KIND OF, APPROACH
TO EDUCATION THAT MADE IT FUN
TO LEARN.
>> Alisyn: YEAH SHE WAS
DESCRIBED AS PASSIONATE
EXTREMELY DEDICATED AND SHE
SENT OUT A LOT OF TWEETS.
ONE OF THE ONES THAT STRUCK ME
WAS ON THE FIRST DAY OF SCHOOL
THIS YEAR, SHE TALKED ABOUT
HOW EXCITED SHE WAS TO WELCOME
THE NEW KINDERGARTENERS IN FOR
THEIR LIFE LONG LOVE OF
LEARNING, SHE HOPED TO BE ABLE
TO STOKE THAT.
ANOTHER TWEET SHE SENT OUT ON
SAFETY AND THIS IS ON OCTOBER
17TH SHE SAID SAFETY FIRST AT
SANDY HOOK.
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL DAY FOR OUR
ANNUAL EVALUATION DRILL.
>> Brian: A LOT OF TIMES
PEOPLE WOULD TRY TO GET INTO
THE BUILDING AND EVEN IF
YOU'RE BILL O'REILLY, YOU'RE
NOT GOING TO GET IN.
THAT'S WHAT SHE SAID ABOUT THE
NEW SAFETY PROCEDURES IN
OCTOBER.
LOOK, PLEASE UNDERSTAND WITH
NEARLY 700 STUDENTS AND A
THOUSAND PARENTS REPRESENTING
500 FAMILIES MOST PARENTS WILL
BE ASKED TO SHOW
IDENTIFICATION, SOME MIGHT BE
INSULTED, BUT UNDERSTAND WHERE
I'M COMING FROM BECAUSE YOU
DON'T WANT THE WRONG GUY
GETTING INTO THE SCHOOL.
AND THAT WAS THE LETTER THAT
THEY SENT OUT WHEN THEY
STARTED THE NEW SYSTEM, WITH
YOU YOU WANTED TO GET INTO THE
SCHOOL, ALL THE DOORS WERE
LOCKED START AGO 9:30 IN THE
MORNING, IF YOU WANTED TO GET
IN, YOU HAD TO GO TO THE FRONT
DOOR, RING THE DOOR BELL AND
THEY WOULD BE BUZZED IN.
YESTERDAY NOBODY BUZZED IN THE
GUY WITH THE GUNS, INSTEAD
BROKE THE GLASS AND CAME IN
AND CONFRONTATION AND THAT
JUST OUTSIDE THE OFFICE WHEN
HE MURDERED THE PRINCIPAL.
>> AND SHE WAS HIRED IN 2010,
ALREADY MAKING IMPACT ON THE
SCHOOL AND SHE WAS JOINED BY
MARY SHERLOCK, 56 YEARS OLD.
BEEN THERE 18 YEARS AND ACCORD
TO GO A FAMILY MEMBER, AND SHE
IS SURVIVED BY A HUSBAND AND
OLDER DAUGHTERS IN THEIR 20'S
AND HEARD THE POPS, AND NOT
SPECIAL TRAINING, BUT WHEN YOU
HEAR THE GUN GO OFF AND YOU
RUN TO THE GUN.
THAT'S INCREDIBLE INSTINCTS.
>> Steve: AND ALSO, WE'VE BEEN
WONDERING WHY WOULD THIS GUY
SHOOT AND MURDER HIS MOTHER
AND THEN GO TO THE SCHOOL?
RIGHT?
AND THE STORY HAS BEEN, YOU
KNOW, SHE HAD BEEN A TEACHER
THERE OR A TEACHER'S AIDE OR
SHE HAD SOME SORT OF A
RELATIONSHIP WITH IT.
AND APPARENTLY WE'VE JUST
HEARD FROM THE SUPERINTENDENT
OF SCHOOLS UP THERE, SHE WAS
NOT ON THE STAFF.
SHE DID NOT HAVE A
RELATIONSHIP WITH THE SCHOOL.
SO, THAT MAKES HIS APPEARANCE
AT THE SCHOOL ABOUT 23 HOURS
AGO, EVEN THE MORE PUZZLING.
AND SANDY HOOK.
>> Steve: SHE'S NOT IN THE
SCHOOL'S DATA BASE.
>> Alisyn: INTERESTING, WELL,
HOPEFULLY AT THE PRESS
CONFERENCE, A REPORTER WILL
HAVE SOME ANSWERS.
AND WE'LL BRING BY DR. MARK
SEGAL.
WE'VE TALKED ABOUT THE PTSD
NOT JUST FOR THE IMMEDIATE
KIDS IN THE SCHOOL AND
IMMEDIATE PARENTS, BUT FOR ALL
OF US NATIONWIDE.
PEOPLE IN CALIFORNIA HAVE
E-MAILED AND PEOPLE IN
WASHINGTON STATE E-MAILED HOW
DEVASTATED THEY ARE BY ALL OF
THIS.
HOW DO YOU START TO ADDRESS
THAT?
>> WELL, ALISYN IT SPANS
OUTWARD.
FOR THE KIDS OF THE SCHOOL
ACCORDING TO THE NATIONAL
CENTER OF PTSD, MANY ARE GOING
TO SUFFER FOR DRAMATIC CHANGES
AND WHEN THEY PLAY, FEEL
AGGRESSIVE AND ANTICIPATE THE
NEXT TRAGEDY, IT'S JUST
TERRIBLE, THEY'RE GOING TO BE
NERVOUS, THEY FEEL A
PREMONITION OF SOMETHING ELSE
COMING ON AND MAY FEEL
SADNESS, ANXIETY.
VERY TOUGH TO GET OVER.
THERAPY WILL BE REQUIRED AND
EVEN FOR KIDS IN THE
NEIGHBORHOOD NOWHERE NEAR THE
SCHOOL, ABOUT 30, 40% OF THEM
WILL FEEL THE SYMPTOMS OF
PTSD, HAVE TROUBLE SLEEPING,
LOW SELF-ESTEEM.
TROUBLE CONNECTING WITH PEOPLE
AND FOR THE REST OF US, IT
DEPENDS ON HOW WE HANDLE THIS,
A LOTS OF US ARE FOCUSED ON
THE MEDIA AND OUR
REPRESENTATION ON TELEVISION.
WHAT ARE WE TELLING OUR
CHILDREN, TO BE EMPATHETIC, TO
CARE ABOUT THE VICTIMS AND NOT
FOCUS SO MUCH ON OURSELVES,
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT OUR KIDS
SCHOOLS AND THE CHANCE OF THIS
HAPPENING AGAIN, LESS THAN 1%
OF ALL HOMICIDES IN THE UNITED
STATES OCCUR AROUND SCHOOLS,
LESS THAN 1%.
IT CERTAINLY DOESN'T SEEM THAT
WAY THIS MORNING AND CERTAINLY
WE HAVE TO REPORT THIS THE WAY
THEY'RE REPORTING IT, I DON'T
WANT MY CHILDREN TO BE AFRAID.
I WANT MY CHILDREN TO CARE
ABOUT THE CHILDREN OUT THERE.
>> Brian: YOU'RE SAYING, YOU
CAN TELL THEM FLAT OUT IT'S
NOT GOING TO HAPPEN TO YOU,
EVEN THOUGH YOU NEVER CAN BE
100% SURE, IT DOESN'T HAPPEN
EVERY DAY, SECOND WORST
MASSACRE IN THE HISTORY OF OUR
COUNTRY WITH EDUCATION, AND
HIT THEM WITH THE STATS.
>> RIGHT, I LIKE EXACTLY THE
WAY YOU PUT THAT.
YOU HAVE TO ANSWER THEIR
QUESTIONS AND YOU HAVE TO
ANSWER THEM HONESTLY, LOOK,
THEY'RE LOOKING HOW YOU'RE
ANSWERING, ARE YOU WORRIED,
LOOK LIKE YOU'RE WORRIED TO
SEND YOUR CHILD TO SCHOOL
TOMORROW, ON MONDAY.
YOU SHOULD THINK THOSE
STATISTICS OUT IN YOUR OWN
BRAIN FIRST THAT IT'S KNOTS
GOING TO HAPPEN THE SCHOOL.
YOU HAVE TO PROJECT CALM AND
CONFIDENCE AND CARING, YOU
WANT YOUR KIDS TO CARE FOR THE
VICTIMS AND YOU CARE FOR THEM.
>> Brian: I WANT TO TALK ABOUT
THE SHOOTER, THE KILLER.
IS IT POSSIBLE, AND GETTING
INSIDE HIS HEAD, IS IT
POSSIBLE THIS GUY IS JUST
EVIL?
TO SIT IN FRONT OF A KID AND
SHOOT AT A CHILD FIVE YEARS
OLD IN THE HEAD, IS IT THAT
SIMPLE?
>> BRIAN WITH ALL OF MY
MEDICAL TRAINING, I CAN LOOK
AT THINGS CLINICALLY AND I CAN
GIVE YOU REASON, BUT I
ABSOLUTELY REFUSE TO LOOK AT A
SITUATION LIKE THIS, WHERE SO
MANY--
SOMEBODY ALLEGEDLY
COLD-BLOODEDLY GUNS DOWN
CHILDREN THERE'S AN ELEMENT OF
EVIL.
I'M NOT GOING TO SAY A MEDICAL
DIAGNOSIS, I DON'T BELIEVE
THERE IS JUST A DISORDER OR AN
AUTISTIC--
THIS SOUNDS LIKE SOMEBODY IS
PSYCHOTIC AND DILUTIONAL AND
THINK THE CHILDREN REPRESENT
SOMETHING ELSE.
>> Alisyn: ISN'T THAT HAD A
PERSONALITY DISORDER.
>> MUCH WORSE.
A 20-YEAR-OLD, I'M THINKING
SCHIZOPHRENIC, BIPOLAR
DISORDER.
SOMEBODY WAS OUT OF TOUCH
COMPLETELY WITH REHE ALT, BUT
THAT DOESN'T LET THAT PERSON
OFF THE HOOK, ALISYN, PLENTY
OF PEOPLE LIKE THAT ARE NOT
GOING AROUND SHOOTING PEOPLE.
>> Steve: A GOOD POINT.
IF YOU'RE JUST JOINING US,
WE'RE AWAITING A PRESS
CONFERENCE AND THE AUTHORITIES
IN CONNECTICUT ARE RELEASING
THE INFORMATION THAT THEY
GATHERED OVERNIGHT AND DR.
SEGAL, YOU KNOW, THE LAST 23
YEARS HAVE BEEN REALLY HARD
FOR 20 SETS OF PARENTS THEY
PUT THEIR KIDS IN FRONT DOOR
OF THAT SCHOOL, YESTERDAY
MORNING ABOUT THIS TIME AND
THEY REMAINED ONNED FLOOR
OVERNIGHT.
AND IT'S, YOU KNOW, AND FOR
THE POLICE TO SAY, TELL US
WHAT YOUR CHILD WAS WEARING
WHEN THEY WENT TO SCHOOL,
THAT'S SO HARD FOR A PARENT
AND FOR THE PARENTS WATCHING
RIGHT NOW, YOU KNOW, I'VE GOT
KIDS WHO WENT TO SCHOOL AFTER
COLUMBINE AND EVERY TIME THERE
WAS ANOTHER SCHOOL SHOOTING
THEY WOULD JUST FREAK OUT.
THEY'D HEAR ABOUT IT AT SCHOOL
AND THEY WORRIED THAT'S GOING
TO HAPPEN TO THEM, EVEN
THOUGH, YOU KNOW, WE DID
DISCUSS WHAT WE'RE SUPPOSED TO
DO.
KIDS WORRY.
>> AND I CAN'T IMAGINE THE
PARENTS HAVING THE COURAGE,
AND THE IDEA OF PUTTING YOUR
KIDS' CAR SEAT IN THE TRUNK
AND KNOWING YOU'RE NEVER GOING
TO LOSE IT.
I HAVE THREE CHILDREN AND I
CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT IT'S LIKE
TO LOSE ONE OF MY CHILDREN AND
FACE THE CAMERAS AND GO
THROUGH A CRIMINAL
INVESTIGATION AND YOU KNOW,
IT'S JUST, THIS IS THE
GREATEST TRAGEDY.
>>.
>> Brian: ON TOP OF THAT, TOO,
AND SYMPATHY, BUT THE DAD,
PETER FINDS OUTS FROM
REPORTERS THAT IT WAS HIS SON
THAT WAS THE ASSAILANT AND
QUICKLY ROLLED UP HIS WINDOW
AND WENT INTO THE HOUSE AND
YOU JUST WONDER AND THE SAME
THING I THOUGHT ABOUT WITH
AURORA AND GABBY GIFFORDS, HOW
MUCH DO THE PARENTS KNOW AND
HOW MUCH DO THEY KNOW WHAT A
DANGER THEIR SON ENDED UP
BEING.
>> THAT'S A TAKE HOME, BRIAN.
YOU WONDER HOW MUCH HELP WE'RE
GETTING IN THE COUNTRY.
ON MEDICATION AND WAS THERE
ENOUGH MENTAL HEALTH.
>> Alisyn: AND DOCTOR ONE LAST
THING IN TERMS OF THE
CHILDREN, IF YOUR KIDS TODAY
HAVE HEARD ANYTHING OR SEEN
ANYTHING AND THEY ASK ABOUT
IT, LESS IS BETTER, BUT YOU
DON'T HAVE TO GIVE THEM LONG
PHILOSOPHICAL DISCUSSIONS OR
EXPLANATIONS.
ANSWER IN ONE SENTENCE
ANSWERS.
>> CERTAINTY, AND ANSWER WITH
CERTAINTY.
BE CAREFUL ABOUT LETTING THEM
SEE THIS OVER AND OVER.
>> AND RON WHEELER IS WITH US
VIA SATELLITE.
>> WE'RE HOPPING TO GET MORE
QUESTIONS ANS
MORNING BY THE STATE POLICE
AND THE LOCAL POLICE THERE.
WHAT'S THE NUMBER ONE THING
YOU THINK THEY'RE GOING TO BE
ABLE TO TELL US AT 8:40 IN THE
MORNING.
>> WHAT WE'RE GOING TO HEAR IN
THE PRESS CONFERENCE, TELL US
HOW MANY ROUNDS WERE FIRED,
PROBABLY.
HOW MANY WEAPONS EVEN THOUGH
WE'VE HEARD IT'S PROBABLY TWO
WEAPONS USE ADDEN THEY KNOW
THAT FOR A FACT NOW AND
THEY'RE GOING TO TELL US
WHETHER ANY OF THE VICTIMS
WERE TARGETED IN THIS SHOOTING
AND THE OTHER VICTIMS WERE
COLLATERAL VICTIMS.
WE'RE GOING TO HEAR THOSE
KINDS OF THINGS AND FIND OUT
AT THIS PRESS CONFERENCE,
WHETHER OR NOT THIS INDIVIDUAL
LEFT ANY NOTES.
WE HAVEN'T HEARD THAT YET, BUT
COULD HAVE LEFT A NOTE I'M
TALKING ABOUT THE SHOOTER.
WHETHER OR NOT HE HAD A
FACEBOOK PAGE, WHAT WAS ON IT.
WHAT IS ON HIS COMPUTER AND
MAYBE NOT SPECIFIC DETAILS
WHAT WAS ON HIS COMPUTER, BUT
WE'RE GOING TO HEAR THOSE
KINDS OF THINGS, WHAT WE NEED
RIGHT NOW IS CLOSURE.
THE FAMILIES NEED CLOSURE,
THEY NEED TO KNOW WHY THIS GUY
DO WHAT HE DID AND WHY DID HE
IN FACT TARGET THIS PARTICULAR
SCHOOL.
I THOUGHT IT WAS INTERESTING,
STEVE.
A FEW MINUTES AGO WHEN BRIAN
TOLD US AND SHARED WITH US THE
NEWS THAT THIS GUY, HIS MOTHER
MAY HAVE NOT EVEN BEEN ON THE
PAYROLL THERE AT THE SCHOOL.
AS YOU KNOW, EVERYBODY HAS
BEEN TALKING ABOUT THAT, SO
WHEN HE SAID THAT I THOUGHT TO
MYSELF OKAY, THEN THERE IS
ANOTHER REASON THEN WHY THIS
GUY SELECTED THAT SCHOOL AND
MAYBE IT'S NOT HIS MOTHER AND
THAT'S WHAT WE HAVE TO FIGURE
OUT.
>> RIGHT.
WE'RE SAYING THAT SHE'S NOT
CURRENTLY ON THE PAYROLL, BUT
COULD HAVE BEEN AS YEAR OR THE
YEAR BEFORE.
AND ALSO PART OF THE STORY
THAT I READ AND I CANNOT
REMEMBER THE PUBLICATION, IS
THAT SHE QUIT TO SPEND MORE
TIME WITH HER SON WHO WAS TO
SAY THE LEAST, A HANDFUL.
AND ACCORDING TO THE NEIGHBORS
THEY KNEW HE WAS A HANDFUL.
>> YOU KNOW, I'M WONDERING IF
THIS GUY USED TO GO BACK AND
FORTH UP TO THAT SCHOOL A LOT
AND MAYBE THE SCHOOL
ENCOURAGED THE MOTHER TO SPEND
MORE TIME WITH HIM AT THE HOME
AND MAYBE THAT TICKED THIS GUY
OFF.
IN A SENSE THAT KIND OF MADE
SENSE.
THERE HAD TO BE SOME REASON,
BRIAN, EVEN THOUGH SHE MAY
HAVE HAVE NOT BEEN CURRENTLY
ON THE PAYROLL, AND WHY HE
DECIDED TO GO YESTERDAY.
AND THAT'S ANOTHER QUESTION,
WHY YESTERDAY?
WHY NOT A WEEK AGO, MAYBE
GETTING THE AMMUNITION, CALMO,
FLAK JACKET.
THESE ARE QUESTIONS THAT
EVERYBODY, INCLUDING THE
FAMILIES NEED TO KNOW AND NEED
TO KNOW RIGHT AWAY.
>> Alisyn: I HAVE A QUESTION
ABOUT HOW THE POLICE WILL
HANDLE THE POLICE CONFERENCE,
BECAUSE THERE BE ARGUABLY NOT
BE A CRIMINAL INVESTIGATION,
BECAUSE THE SHOOTER KILLED
HIMSELF SO THEY DON'T NEED TO
BE KEEPING THINGS CLOSE TO
THEIR VEST IN TERMS OF
INFORMATION ABOUT HIM.
WILL THAT MAKE THE POLICE LESS
HAM STRUNG AT THIS PRESS
CONFERENCE?
WILL THEY BE ABLE TO GIVE THE
PUBLIC MUCH MORE INFORMATION
THAN THEY WOULD IF THEY HAD
SOMEBODY IN CUSTODY RIGHT NOW?
>> YES AND NO.
LET ME QUICKLY EXPLAIN WHAT I
MEAN BY THAT ALISYN.
THIS IS A CRIMINAL
INVESTIGATION, YES, WE DO KNOW
THAT THE SHOOTER, ALLEGED
SHOOTER SHOT AND KILLED
HIMSELF.
WHAT WE DON'T KNOW, ALISYN,
WHETHER OR NOT THERE WAS
ANYBODY AFFILIATED WITH THIS
GUY THAT STILL MAY BE OUT
THERE.
WE DON'T KNOW THAT SO THE
POLICE HAVE TO BE A LITTLE
CAUTIOUS, ALISYN IN TERMS OF
HOW MUCH INFORMATION THEY GIVE
TO THE GENERAL PUBLIC.
THEY'LL SHARE A LOT MORE
INFORMATION, JUST SO YOU I
DON'T, SHARE A LOT MORE
INFORMATION WITH THE DESECEDEN S
DECEDENTS' FAMILIES THAN US.
AND IT COULD BE WEEKS, OR
MONTHS.
>> I'M LOOKING AT THE NEWTOWN
PATCH THERE, THE LOCAL
NEWSPAPER AND SAID AT THIS
POINT ANY KIND OF A MOTIVE IS
MURKY, UNCLEAR.
WITH REGARDING THE PRESS
CONFERENCE AT THAT WE'RE
SUPPOSED TO HAPPEN 45 MINUTES
AGO AND STILL WAITING FOR IT.
IT SAYS THAT THE POLICE ARE
WORKING BACKWARDS TO PIECE
TOGETHER THE WHY'S BEHIND THE
SHOOTING.
EXPLAIN THAT, WOULD YOU,
WORKING BACKWARDS?
>> YES, IN EVERY CRIMINAL
INVESTIGATION, GUYS, GOOD
INFORMATION YOU ALWAYS WANT TO
WORK BACKWARDS.
YOU NEVER MAKE ASSUMPTIONS, IF
YOU MAKE ASSUMPTIONS THAT
MEANS YOU'RE WORKING FORWARD,
YOU THINK THIS IS WHAT
HAPPENED.
WHEN YOU WORK BACKWARDS YOU'RE
TRYING TO TRACE THIS GUY'S
LIFE WHERE WAS HE AT THE NIGHT
BEFORE THE SHOOTING OCCURRED?
WHO WAS HE TALKING TO?
THEY HAVE HIS CELL PHONE AND
EVERY OFF HIS CELL PHONE AND
CALLING THOSE FOLKS AND THE
FBI IS AT THESE FOLKS' HOUSES
AND THAT'S WHAT THEY MEAN,
THAT'S THE BEST WAY TO TRY TO
FIND SOME UNDERSTANDING TO
FIND WHY THIS GUY DID WHAT HE
DID.
>> THE LAST QUESTION BEFORE WE
GO TO THE PRESS CONFERENCE AND
BRING IN A REPORTER FROM THE
NEWTOWN PATCH, FROM YOUR
EXPERIENCE, WHEN A PRESS
CONFERENCE IS 45 MINUTES LATE
AFTER A HORRIFIC CRIME LIKE WE
JUST SAW PERPETRATED, DOES IT
USUALLY MEAN THAT SOMETHING IS
UNFOLDING?
>> YES AND NO AGAIN, BRIAN.
AND I APOLOGIZE FOR THAT
ANSWER, YES AND NO, BUT THE
REASON I'M SAYING THAT, I
WOULDN'T READ TOO MUCH IN THE
FACT THAT THE PRESSER IS
TAKING A LITTLE BIT OF TIME.
I THINK THE ONLY REASON THE
PRESSER IS TAKING A LITTLE BIT
MORE TIME BECAUSE THEY HAVE TO
BE CAREFUL NOW, GUYS, THEY
HAVE TO BE VERY CAREFUL IN
TERMS OF HOW MUCH INFORMATION
THEY GIVE TO THE GENERAL
PUBLIC.
WHY?
BECAUSE THIS IS STILL A
CRIMINAL INVESTIGATION AND I
BELIEVE THE POLICE DEPARTMENT,
THE FBI AND THE PROSECUTOR IN
THAT COMMUNITY THERE, THEY'RE
GOING THROUGH ALL THE
INFORMATION TO DECIDE EXACTLY
WHAT THEY WANT TO RELEASE AND
WOULDN'T READ TOO MUCH INTO
THE FACT QUITE YET THIS IS
TAKING A WHILE.
>> Alisyn: THANK YOU, STANDING
BY AND WE'LL TALK TO YOU AFTER
THE PRESS CONFERENCE.
OUR NEXT GUEST WAS ON THE
GROUND AFTER HEARING THE NEWS,
NEWTOWN LOCAL EDITOR FOR THE
PATCH NEWSPAPER.
AARON, GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
TELL US WHAT HAPPENED WHEN YOU
ARRIVED ON THE SCENE
YESTERDAY.
>> FIRST THING ARRIVING, IT
WAS A SURPRISINGLY ORGANIZED
CHAOS, THERE WERE PARENTS
EVERYWHERE JUST WAITING TO
HEAR WHAT HAPPENED AND TO TRY
TO FIND OUT WHAT HAD HAPPENED
WITH THEIR CHILDREN, IF THEIR
CHILDREN WERE OKAY.
AND PARENTS STANDING AROUND
TRYING TO CONSOLE EACH OTHER.
AND AFTER A TIME, THE POLICE
START TODAY EVACUATE THE
CHILDREN, THEY WERE BROUGHT AT
ONE CLASS AT A TIME IN ORDER
TO ACCOUNT FOR EVERYONE, AND
WE WERE ABLE TO SEE A LOT OF
FAMILIES REUNITED, A LOT OF
JOY, TEMPERED JOY AS THEY
REALIZED THAT OTHER FAMILIES
AROUND THEM WEREN'T BEING RUE
UNITED.
AND LATER IN THE DAY WE SAW
MORE PARENTS BROUGHT IN AND
SUBSEQUENTLY LEAVING WITHOUT
THEIR CHILDREN.
>> Brian: I'VE GOT TO ASK YOU
A QUESTION.
IF YOU DON'T KNOW THAT'S FINE.
SO MANY CONTRADICTORY WRITTEN
BY REPUTABLE SOURCES.
FIRST OFF, CAN YOU TELL ME IF
HIS MOTHER WAS ACTUALLY
ASSOCIATED WITH THE SCHOOL AT
ALL?
IF SO, WHEN?
>> I CAN'T TELL YOU EXACTLY
WHEN.
WE KNOW SHE WAS AT SOME POINT
A TEACHER WITH THE SCHOOL.
AND AS YOU HEARD, WE'VE HEARD
AS WELL, SHE NO LONGER WORKS
THERE OFFICIALLY, BUT AT SOME
POINT SHE WAS WITH THE SCHOOL
SYSTEM.
>> Brian: BUT WAS A TEACHER OR
COULD SHE HAVE BEEN AN AIDE OR
JUST A SUBSTITUTE?
>> NOW, I BELIEVE TEACHER, BUT
I'M NOT 100% CONFIDENT ON
THAT.
>> ALL RIGHT.
AARON, WE UNDERSTAND THAT THE
PRINCIPAL, WHO WAS TRAGICALLY
MURDERED YESTERDAY, HAD
RECENTLY INSTALLED THAT BUZZER
SYSTEM WHERE IF YOU WANTED TO
GET IN THE SCHOOL AFTER SCHOOL
STARTED YOU HAD TO GET BUZZED
IN.
IT SOUNDS LIKE THIS ADAM LANZA
ACTUALLY BROKE THE WINDOW.
DO YOU KNOW THE EXTENT OF THE
PRECAUTIONS THAT THE SCHOOL
HAD MADE IN ADVANCE OF THE
MASSACRE YESTERDAY?
>> WELL, IT'S SIMILAR TO A LOT
OF THE SAFETY MEASURES BEING
INSTALLED IN A LOT OF SCHOOLS
IN THE AREA.
AND ACROSS THE INAUGURATION.
BUZZERS ARE BECOMING MORE AND
MORE TRADITIONAL WAY OF MAKING
SURE THAT CHILDREN ARE SAFE.
BUT, AS WE SAW YESTERDAY,
THERE'S NO WAY TO KEEP
EVERYONE SAFE 100% OF THE
TIME.
PEOPLE LIKE THIS WILL FIND A
WAY.
>> Alisyn: AND IF SOMEONE
WANTS TO BREAK IN, HE JUST
BROKE IN.
AARON, HAVE YOU AT YOUR PAPER
BEEN ABLE TO FLESH OUT ANY
MORE PICTURES OF THE SHOOTER,
OF ADAM.
WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT HIS
BACKGROUND?
>> AT THIS POINT, NO, WE
HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE TO GET ANY
NEW INFORMATION THAT ISN'T
ALREADY OUT THERE AND WE ARE
HEAPING TO GET A LITTLE MORE
FROM THE PRESS CONFERENCE
WE'RE WAITING ON.
>> Brian: SHOULD BE
INTERESTING.
AND GIVE US AN IDEA THE PEOPLE
OF NEWTON--
NEWTOWN, I SHOULD SAY, TO HAVE
TWO HANDGUNS AND A RIFLE
REGISTERED LEGALLY TO SOMEONE.
IS THERE A LOT OF HUNTING
GOING ON IN THAT AREA.
>> THERE'S CERTAINLY HUNTING
IN CONNECTICUT AND THIS AREA,
IT'S VERY WOODED.
THERE'S A LARGE DEER
POPULATION AND WE HAVE
CONTROLLED DEER HUNTS EVERY
YEAR, AND GUN OWNERSHIP IS NOT
NECESSARILY UNUSUAL IN THIS
AREA.
AND THAT SAID, IT'S ALSO NOT
PARTICULARLY PREVALENT EITHER.
>> AND NEWTOWN LOCAL EDITOR OF
THE PATCH.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
>> THANK YOU.
AND NOW WE'RE JOINED ON THE
SET BY THE SECURITY EXPERT AS
WELL, HARRY, WHEN WE SPOKE A
COUPLE OF HOURS AGO.
>> RIGHT.
>> Steve: THE NEWS FROM THE
NEW YORK TIMES HAD BEEN THAT
APPARENTLY THIS GUY CAME TO
THE FRONT DOOR AND BECAUSE HE
WAS THE SON AFTER WOMAN WHO
HAD WORKED IN THE SCHOOL HE
GOT BUZZED IN.
AND AS IT TURNS OUT THAT'S NOT
STORY.
APPARENTLY HE APPEARED HAD
CAMOUFLAGE ON AND GUNS IN HIS
POCKET AND BROKE THROUGH THE
GLASS.
IT SOUNDS LIKE THIS PARTICULAR
SCHOOL DID HAVE AN ACTION
PLAN.
>> YES, IT DEFINITELY DID.
AND I'VE GOT TO TELL YOU HOW
IMPRESSED I AM WITH THAT THIRD
GRADE TEACHER.
>> Alisyn: MY GOODNESS.
>> I COULD NOT HAVE TAUGHT HER
ANY BETTER.
>> Steve: KIDS UP ON THE
TOILET AND LOCKED THEMSELVES
IN THE BATHROOM.
>> RIGHT.
>> SHE DOESN'T REALIZE HOW
MUCH OF A HERO SHE IS.
SHE KEPT THAT DOOR LOCKED.
THE SHOOTER TRIED TO ENTER THE
BATHROOM, ALL RIGHT, IT
APPEARS AND HE DIDN'T HAVE THE
FORETHOUGHT TO SHOOT THROUGH
THE DOOR.
HE SAW THAT AS A WAY OF
IMPEDING WHAT HE WAS DOING,
ALL RIGHTS, AND DECIDED TO
TURN AROUND AND FIND AN EASIER
TARGET.
ALL RIGHT AND THAT'S WHAT
HAPPENED.
AND THAT TEACHER, IS SHE'S A
HERO AND SHOULD BE VERY PROUD
OF HERSELF.
>> AS IS THE MUSIC TEACHER,
TOO, SOMETHING VERY SIMILAR
AND HEARD BANGING ON THE DOOR.
>> IN TERMS OF THIS CRIME, IS
IT FROM YOUR EXPERIENCE,
ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE TO IMAGINE
SOMEONE KILLING IN THIS, IN
THIS COLD BLOOLDED WAY, FOR
THE FIRST TIME AND THEN
KILLING THEMSELVES?
IS IT POSSIBLE TO SEE THIS
HAPPENING, THAT THAT HAPPENED
ONE DAY WITH NO CRIMINAL
RECORD?
>> RIGHT, IT HAPPENS ALL THE
TIME AND A LONG TIME AGO WHEN
I WAS A DETECTIVE, I STOPPED
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHY
PEOPLE DO THINGS.
IT'S JUST TOTALSLY INSANE.
I CAN'T SEE SOMEBODY STANDING
THERE WITH A CLASSROOM FULL OF
CHILDREN AND SITTING THERE AND
EXECUTING THEM AND LOOKING AT
THEIR BEAUTIFUL FACES.
AND IT'S JUST SOMETHING THAT
YOU CAN'T THINK ABOUT.
NOW?
AND AS A DETECTIVE, YOU KNOW,
I'M USED TO SEEING BODIES, YOU
KNOW, OF ADULTS ALL THE TIME,
BUT YOU KNOW, WHEN IT'S A
CHILD, YOU NEVER GET OVER IT.
THAT'S SOMETHING YOU DON'T GET
USED TO.
I REMEMBER THE FIRST DEAD
CHILD I SAW WHEN I FIRST
BECAME A COP IN 1978--
>> I WANTED TO ASK YOU ABOUT
THAT.
I WANT TODAY ASK YOU ABOUT
HOW CAN THE NEWTOWN POLICE
EVER BE MENTALLY PREPARED FOR
WHAT THEY ENCOUNTER WHEN THEY
RAN INTO THE SCHOOL YESTERDAY.
WHAT HAPPENED?
THE NEWTOWN POLICE TAKE
PSYCHOLOGICAL TRAINING AND BE
COMPOSED AT A SCENE LIKE THAT.
>> NOT THAT I'M AWARE OF.
WE NEVER RECEIVED ANY KIND OF
TRAINING.
NOW WHAT THEY'LL DO, PROBABLY
HAVE THOSE POLICE OFFICERS
SPEAK TO PEOPLE TO HELP THEM
DEAL WITH THIS.
CAN YOU IMAGINE THE FIRST
RESPONDING OFFICER TO WALK
INTO THAT CHARM AND SEE ALL OF
THOSE CHILDREN DID HE
UNDERSTAND?
I MEAN, I CAN'T -- I CAN'T
FATHOM THAT AT ALL.
>> AND IN THREE MINUTES THE
ENTIRE OPERATION, DOES THAT
SURPRISE YOU?
>> I TELL WHAT YOU, THE MOST
DANGEROUS PEOPLE IN AN ACTIVE
SHOOTER INCIDENTS IS THE FIRST
TWO AND THREE MINUTES.
WHEN I WAS LISTENING TO THE
POLICE RADIO ONLINE IT APPEARS
THE SHOOTING WAS DONE WHEN THE
POLICE ALREADY RESPONDED.
>> Steve: IT WAS THAT FAST.
AND TODAY, LOOK AT SOME OF THE
BLOGS ARE ALREADY TALKING
ABOUT, DO WE NEED BETTER
SECURITY, DO WE NEED TO
CONTROL GUNS?
AND YOU KNOW, AND THAT'S, THAT
JUST HAPPENS IN CERTAIN PARTS
OF THE INTERNET.
>> RIGHT.
>> Steve: WHEN YOU LOOK AT
9/11, I MEAN, 3000 PEOPLE WIND
UP DYING NOT BECAUSE OF GUNS,
BUT BECAUSE OF BOMBS.
>> AND THAT'S A DEBATE ABOUT
THAT.
>> Steve: THERE NEEDS TO BE A
DEBATES ABOUT THE CULTURE.
>> WITHOUT A DOUBT, WITHOUT A
DOUBT.
AND, BUT YOU'VE GOT TO PUT THE
BLAME WHERE IT BELONGS, EVIL
ON THE SHOOTER, THE BAD GUY.
EVIL.
>> EXACTLY.
>> Brian: RIGHT, BUT IN TERMS
OF HAVING A GLOCK AND ANOTHER
WEAPON, I'M NOT A BIG GUN GUY,
I DON'T KNOW--
ANDED BIG GAME RIFLE IF I TOLD
YOU THEY WERE LOCATED IN
CONNECTICUT, DOES THAT REMIND
YOU OF SOMETHING, A TYPICAL OF
CONNECTICUT.
>> I'M SURE THERE'S HUNTERS IN
>> Steve: THEY'RE LEGAL GUNS.
>> THE WEAPONS ARE LEGAL THE
MERE FACT THAT THIS KID HAD
ACCESS TO THESE WEAPONS, ALL
RIGHT, IF HE HAD SOME KIND OF
PSYCHOLOGICAL PROBLEM IS A
PROBLEM FOR ME.
HOW COME THE GUNS WEREN'T
LOCKED UP.
WE DON'T KNOW FOR SURE THEY
WERE OR WEREN'T.
>> HE LIVED IN THE HOUSE WITH
HIS MOTHER.
>> AND PROBABLY REGISTERED TO
HIS MOM AND THESE ARE
QUESTIONS NA NEED TO BE
ANSWERED AND SOMEBODY WHO BY
MANY ACCOUNTS TODAY DOES SEEM
TO HAVE BEEN MENTALLY
DISTURBED AND HIS BROTHER
DESCRIBED A PERSONALITY
DISORDER, WHY HE WOULD HAVE
ACCESS TO THESE AND THAT WOULD
MEAN--
AN INVESTIGATION WOULD START.
>> THERE'S GOING TO BE A LOT
OF QUESTIONS REGARDING THIS
AND TRYING TO FIND OUT WHY
THIS HAPPENED.
I MEAN THIS, GUY, IT WILL BE A
NOTE, DID HE HAVE A MANIFESTO,
ALL RIGHT?
AND YOU KNOW, ALL THE
PSYCHOLOGISTS AND
PSYCHIATRISTS ARE GOING TO
LOOK AT THIS AND TRY TO--
IF THIS GUY DIDN'T LEAVE A
NOTE, ALL RIGHT, IF THERE
WASN'T ANY SIGN, BUT I'M SURE
THERE WERE SIGNS THIS GUY WAS
A LUNATIC?
ARE WE GOING TO KNOW WHY THE
MAN DID THIS.
HE'S DEAD NOW.
>> Brian: IF YOU'RE A FIRST
TIME KILLER, AND WERE DRUGS
INVOLVED?
WERE YOU ALMOST A WALKING
ZOMBIE, THAT OUT OF YOUR MIND.
WOULD THAT SURPRISE YOU THERE
WERE LEGAL DRUGS INVOLVED?
>> THAT WOULDN'T SURPRISE ME,
APPARENTLY HAD SOME TYPES OF
PSYCHOLOGICAL ISSUES AND ON
SOME TYPE OF MEDICATION, MAYBE
THE MEDICATION M A SIDE
EFFECTS FOR HIM TO ACT LIKE A
COMPLETE LUNATIC AND DO
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
THE MERE FACT THAT THIS GUY
WOKE UP THAT MORNING AND SHOT
HIS MOTHER AND DECIDED TO GO
TO THE SCHOOL AND KILL
CHILDREN, IT'S JUST BEYOND--
PREMEDITATED OR NOT.
>> I THINK IT'S PRE HE
MEDITATED.
I DON'T THINK HE JUST WOKE UP
THAT MORNING, HE HAD THE WHOLE
OUTFIT, HE HAD THE WEAPONS AND
WOKE UP.
AND FORETHOUGHT TO SHOOT HIS
MOTHER, GETS IN HIS CAR AND
MAKE HIS WAY TO THE SCHOOL AND
WHAT I THINK BROKE GLASS TO
GET INTO THE SCHOOL.
ALL RIGHT?
AND JUST WENT TO THE OFFICE
AND SHOTS UP THE OFFICE WITH
THE TEACHERS THERE AND THEN HE
SAID, WELL, LET ME GO TO A
KINDERGARTEN CLASSROOM OR
CLASS AND SHOOT SOME CHILDREN,
I MEAN.
>> AND HE KNEW EXACTLY WHAT HE
WAS DOING.
>> I THINK HE KNEW EXACTLY
WHAT HE WAS DOING.
>> AND THE FACT THAT HE HAD TO
BREAK THE GLASS TO GET INTO
THE SCHOOL AND SO MANY--
WE TALKED A LITTLE AGO,
APPARENTLY SOMEBODY IN THE
OFFICE PUSHED DOWN THE BUTTON
ON THE PUBLIC ADDRESS SYSTEM
AND PEOPLE THROUGHOUT THE
BUILDING HEARD A SCREAM AND
GUNSHOTS AND STARTED LOCKING
DOORS AND THEN, YOU SALUTE
SOME OF THE TEACHERS AS HEROES
BECAUSE THEY DID EXACTLY THE
RIGHT THING.
IN THE FACE AFTER GUY WITH A
BUNCH OF GUNS.
>> YEAH.
>> AND THEY STEPPED UP.
>> AN EVIL MAN WITH GUNS.
>> RIGHT.
>> Brian: WHAT SHOULD SCHOOLS
ALL AROUND THE COUNTRY -- THIS
HAPPENED IN AN INNER CITY
THEY'D GO WELL, THAT'S WHY
THEY HAVE MEDAL DETECTORS AND
SECURITY AND JOE CLARK,
EVERYTHING HE DID TO REIN IN A
BAD AREA AND TURN AROUND A
COMMUNITY.
WITH IT HAPPENING IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT YOU KNOW PEOPLE
ARE GOING TO RESPOND AND
PRINCIPALS ARE GOING TO BE
RESPOND AND THEY MIGHT BE
HAVING MEETINGS TODAY.
WHAT WOULD YOU HOPE THEY TAKE
OUT OF THE MEETINGS?
>> WE'RE GOING TO GO BACK AND
TAKE A LOOK HOW EVERYTHING
HAPPENED.
ALL RIGHT?
IT APPEARS TO ME, HE HAD TO
BREAK THE GLASS TO GET IN.
AEN SO MAYBE THEY NEED TO
REINFORCE THE DOOR GLASS AND
IF THIS GUY COULDN'T HAVE
GOTTEN OUT OF THE BUILDING,
THIS MIGHT NOT HAVE HAPPENED
AND THE POLICE MIGHT RESPOND
IF THEY SAW SOMEBODY OUTSIDE
AND WE WOULDN'T HAVE THE
TRAGEDY THAT WE HAD TODAY.
ALL RIGHT?
AND WE ALSO PROBABLY NEED TO
REINFORCE THE CLASSROOMS A
LITTLE BIT.
YEAH, AND THAT'S PRETTY COST
EFFECTIVE.
>> AND RIGHT, EXACTLY, AND
MAKE IT A SAFE ROOM AND PUT
SOME REALLY GOOD DOORS LIKE I
SAID THE FIRST TWO OR THREE
MINUTES ARE MOST IMPORTANT AND
WHEN MOST THE KILLING IS DONE.
WE'VE GOT TO BE ABLE TO HOLD
OFF THAT GUY FOR A POLICE
RESPONSE TIME.
IF WE'RE ABLE TO DO THAT, WE
COULD SAVE LIFERS.
>> OF COURSE, YOU'RE
SUGGESTING SECURITY EXPERT.
>> CORRECT.
>> Alisyn: AND OUR DOCTORS AND
PSYCHOLOGIST HAVE TOLD US,
COVERAGE MORE AND MORE SADLY,
TRAGICALLY ON THE NEWS, IT'S
EXTREMELY RARE SO TO HAVE
EVERY SCHOOL BEEFING UP THE
SECURITY AND REINFORCED GLASS,
IS THAT THE RIGHT THING OR
WILL BAD GUYS ALWAYS FIND--
>> FIGURE A WAY IN.
>> THE TARGET.
>> THEY SPECIFICALLY GO FOR A
SOFT TARGET, AN UNPROTECTED
TARGET.
SO, MAYBE, IN GUY WENT
SPECIFICALLY TO THIS SCHOOL
BECAUSE OF WHAT I AM A HEARING
FROM SOME OF THE PEOPLE YOU
HAVE SPEAKING HERE, BECAUSE HE
HAD SOME KIND OF CONNECTION
WITH THAT SCHOOL WITH THE
MOTHER.
ALL RIGHT?
SO THEREFORE, THIS WAS HIS
TARGET.
IF HE COULD NOT HAVE GOTTEN IN
THERE, WHERE WAS HE GOING TO
GO FROM THERE?
SHOT HIMSELF IN FRONT OF THE
SCHOOL?
I DON'T KNOW, I DON'T HAVE A
CRYSTAL BALL, BUT THE WHOLE
THING, NOW, IS THAT THE SCHOOL
SHOULD TAKE SOME TYPE OF
ACTION AT LEAST SOMETHING, YOU
KNOW?
IF NOT APPARENTLY THIS SCHOOL
LOOKS LIKE IT WAS VERY
PREPARED, AND THE TEACHERS
REALLY KNEW HOW TO REACT.
>> IT'S A DOUBLE EDGED SWORD.
AND CUTTING BUDGETS AND AREN'T
LOOKING TO BOLSTER THE GLASS
AND THE KIDS, MIGHT NOT
HAPPEN.
>> HARRY HAUCK, A FORMER NEW
YORK CITY POLICE DEPARTMENT,
EXPERT AS WELL.
ALL RIGHT IT'S NINE O'CLOCK IN
NEW YORK CITY.
>> WE BEGIN THE HOUR WE'RE
AWAITING A LIVE PRESS
CONFERENCE OUT OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT AND EXPECT TO
LEARN NEW DETAILS ABOUT THE
VICTIMS IN THE HORRIBLE
TRAGICER AND THE SHOOTER WHO
TOOK THE LIVES OF 26 PEOPLE.
INCLUDING 20 CHILDREN.
AS YOU SEE, EVERYONE THOUGHT
IT WAS GOING TO START AN HOUR
AGO, WE'RE GOING LIVE TO THE
PRESSER AS SOON AS IT STARTS,
THIS IS UNFOLDING, A VERY LIVE
INVESTIGATION, A LOT OF MOVING
PARTS AND I IMAGINE IT'S GOING
TO BE SUBSTANTIVE AND THAT'S
WHAT WE'RE WAITING FOR,
BECAUSE THEY COULD SEE
THOUSANDS OF MEMBERS OF THE
NATIONAL PRESS.
I ALSO SEE THAT THERE'S PRIME
MINISTERS AND PRESIDENTS FROM
AROUND THE GLOBE REACHING OUT
AND EXPRESSING THEIR SUPPORT
IN AMERICA AND THE HORROR OVER
IN THE U.K., DAVID CAMERON AS
WELL AS THE PRESIDENT
AUSTRALIA.
>> Steve: IT HAPPENED 23 HOURS
AND 30 MINUTES AGO WHEN ADAM
LANZA, 20 YEARS OLDS WALKED
INTO NA SCHOOL AFTER HE BROKE
THE GLASS OUT AFTER HE
MURDERED HIS MOTHER AND SHOT
DEAD 20 CHILDREN AND SIX
ADULTS AND HEARD GREAT STORIES
OF HEROISM.
THINGS THAT TEACHERS AND
MEMBERS OF THAT PARTICULAR
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
THE THINGS THAT THEY DID, A
LOT OF THEM DID THE RIGHT
STUFF.
UNFORTUNATELY, THIS WAS A GUY
INTENT ON KILLING.
>> Alisyn: WE'LL GET TO THE
STORIES ABOUT THE TEACHERS AND
THE STUDENTS THERE, BUT FIRST
LET'S JUST TALK ABOUT WHO ADAM
LANZA IS, BECAUSE OF COURSE,
EVERYONE WANTS TO KNOW IF
THERE WAS A SPARK, A SIGN
WHERE SOMEBODY COULD HAVE SEEN
WHAT WAS GOING TO COME.
HE'S 20 YEARS OLD.
PARENTS DIVORCED IN 2009.
HE'S LIVED ALONE WITH HIS
MOTHER IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
AND HIS DAD LIVED IN STANFORD
AND BROTHER.
AND HIS BROTHER 24 YEARS OLD.
RYAN, LIVED IN HOBOKEN.
HE BELIEVED HIS BROTHER WAS
SOMEWHERE ON THE AUTISM
SPECTRUM, MIGHT HAVE HAD AS
PERFECTI
ASPERGER'S.
AND HE WAS A COMPUTER NERD AND
LOVE VIDEO TECHNOLOGY.
>> GAMER.
>> Alisyn: SOME NUMBERS SAID
STRANGE.
>> FOUND HIM STRANGE.
AS EARLY AS 7TH GRADE WE USED
TO CARRY KNAPSACKS TO SCHOOL
AND HE'D CARRY A BRIEFCASE AND
HE WAS PAINFULLY SHOW AND
FEARED SOMEBODY MIGHT TALK TO
HIM.
AND A QUOTE THAT STOOD OUT TO
ME IN THE DAILY NEWS, ONE OF
THE CLASSMATES WHO HAPPENS TO
BE HIS NEIGHBOR NOW, AS
HORRIBLE AS THIS IS, I CAN'T
SAY I AM SURPRISED.
HE SHOULD BURN IN HELL.
SO I CAN'T SAY I'M SURPRISED
INDICATES THAT NOT ONLY WAS
THIS GUY BASICALLY SHY, BUT
PAINFULLY DANGEROUS.
>> Steve: AND HE LOOKED
DANGEROUS YESTERDAY WHEN HE
ARRIVED AT THE SCHOOL, BLACK
CAMOUFLAGE AND SEMI AUTOMATIC
PISTOLS AND RIFFLE AS WELL.
JUST IMAGINE IF YOU LIVED
NEARBY AND YOUR SISTER IS IS
IN THE THIRD OR FOURTH GRADE
AT THAT SCHOOL AND YOU HEAR
GUNSHOTS.
WELL, THAT WAS THE STORY OF A
YOUNG MAN WHO'S, YOU KNOW,
BROTHER TO A LITTLE GIRL WHO
WENT TO THAT SCHOOL.
HE HEARD THE GUNSHOTS
YESTERDAY AT ABOUT THIS TIME
AND RAN FOR THE SCHOOL TO SEE
IF HIS SISTER WAS OKAY.
HE JOINED US ABOUT TWO HOURS
AGO RIGHT HERE ON "FOX &
FRIENDS" AND HERE IS A LOOK AT
THEIR STORY.
>> SHE WAS IN ART CLASS AND
THE INTERCOM CAME ON, WHERE
SHE HEARD A SCREAM AND A
BULLET.
AND THAT'S WHEN THE SCHOOL
WENT INTO LOCKDOWN AND WHAT
ULTIMATELY HAPPENED WAS
BECAUSE SHE WAS IN THE ART
CLASS, THEY LOCKED THE DOORS,
BUT ONE OF THE DOORS IN THE
ART CLASS DID NOT LOCK
ACCORDING TO WHAT SHE SAID.
SO, YEAH, SO THEY HAD TO GO
INTO SOME SORT OF SMALL ROOM,
A CLOSET, I'M NOT EXACTLY SURE
HOW SHE DETAIL IT HAD, BUT
THEY HAD TO GO INTO A SMALL
ROOM AND STAY QUIET.
>> Alisyn: AND HE WAS HAPPY TO
REPORT THAT HIS SISTER WAS
OKAY AND OBVIOUSLY, VERY
SHAKEN UP AND THE LONG-TERM
RAMIFICATIONS WILL BE WITH
THIS.
WE HAD GOVERNOR MIKE HUCKABEE
ON A SHORT TIME AGO AND HE'S
TAKING HEAT ONLINE ON THE
INTERNET AND HE CAME OUT AND
SAID PART THIS HAVE IS BECAUSE
WE DON'T HAVE ENOUGH RELIGION
IN OUR CULTURE.
HE WAS EXPLAINED ABOUT WHAT HE
THINKS ABOUT OUR CULTURE AND
HOW IT COULD LEAD TO THIS.
AND KEEP IT HERE.
>> YESTERDAY I WAS ON NEIL
CAVUTO AND HE ASKED ME, NOW
WHERE WAS GOD AND I SAID WE'VE
SYSTEMATICALLY REMOVED HIM
FROM OUR CULTURE AND FROM OUR
SCHOOLS AND I'VE BEEN BARRAGED
BY PEOPLE WHO SAID IF WE'VE
H
HAD--
IF WE AS A CULTURES DECIDE WE
DON'T WANT VALUES AND SAY SOME
THINGS ARE ALWAYS RIGHT,
ALWAYS WRONG.
WHEN WE DIVORCE OURSELVES FROM
A BASIC SENSE OF WHAT WE WOULD
CALL, I WOULD SAY COLLECTIVE
MORALITY WE AGREE ON CERTAIN
PRINCIPLES TO BE TRUE ALWAYS,
THEN WE CREATE A CULTURE, NOT
THAT IT SPECIFICALLY CREATES
THIS CRIME, IT DOESN'T.
BUT IT CREATES AN ATMOSPHERE
IN WHICH EVIL AND VIOLENCE ARE
REMOVED FROM OUR SENSE OF
RESPONSIBILITIES.
>> Brian: THERE WAS A LOT OF
VALUES AND A LOT OF GREAT
ACTION UNDER PRESSURE THAT WE
DID SEE YESTERDAY.
BECAUSE THEY WERE PRESSED INTO
ACTION.
THE TOWN OF NEWTOWN, I FIND
FASCINATING.
IT'S ABOUT 20,000 PEOPLE
THERE, 25,000 PEOPLE, ONLY 60
SQUARE MILES, IT'S A
RELATIVELY AFFLUENT COMMUNITY.
108,000 IS THE AVERAGE INCOME
THERE.
45% OF THE HOUSEHOLDS INCLUDE
KIDS UNDER 18 AND WHEN YOU
TALK ABOUT ANCILLARY DAMAGE
AND COLLATERAL, PSYCHOLOGICAL
DAMAGE A LOT OF FAMILIES
EXPLAINING TO DO AND
TWO-THIRDS OF THE RESIDENTS
ARE UNDERAGE 44.
YOUNG EMERGING.
>> Alisyn: YOU MOVE THERE
BECAUSE YOU HAVE KIDS THERE
AND WANT TO GO TO THE SCHOOLS
AND DEDICATED TEACHERS AND
PRINCIPALS LIKE THE ONES WE
SAW YESTERDAY AND KNOW YOUR
KIDS WILL BE SAFE FOR THAT,
AND WHEN YOU SEND THEM OFF TO
SCHOOL IN THE MORNING AND THEY
GO TO KINDERGARTEN.
>> THERE'S A GREAT COLUMN IN
THE NEW YORK DAILY NEWS THIS
MORNING AND ONE OF THE
COLUMNISTS WENT OVER TO THE
BLUE COLONY DINER THERE IN
NEWTOWN AND A WAITRESS TOLD A
SORRY SHE WAS TALKING TO ONE
OF HER REGULAR CUSTOMERS WHO
HAD BEEN TALKING TO HIS GOOD
FRIEND WHOSE CHILD WAS
MURDERED YESTERDAY AND HE SAID
HIS BUDDY WAS UNCONSOLABLE,
OBVIOUSLY, DIDN'T WANT TO GO
ON LIVING, SAID HE WANTED TO
JUMP OFF A BRIDGE AND DIDN'T
WANT TO LIVE ANYMORE WITHOUT
HIS LITTLE GIRL ESPECIALLY AT
CHRISTMAS TIME.
THAT DAD JUST WANTED TO DIE.
>> Brian: RIGHT, INSTEAD OF
GOING OUT AND SHOPPING FOR
CHRISTMAS PRESENTS, A LOT OF
THE FAMILIES ARE SHOPPING FOR
SOMETHING TO BURY THEIR
CHILDREN IN AND IT'S
UNBELIEVABLE THE CHANNING OF
EVENTS AND HOW QUICK SOMETHING
COULD TURN AROUND.
>> Alisyn: WHEN GOVERNOR
HUCKABEE WAS ON AND TALKING
ABOUT THE CULTURE.
IT HEARTS TO MAKE SENSE THAT
IT HAPPENS.
WE KNOW THAT IT HAPPENS IN THE
UNITED STATES MORE AND
ELSEWHERE, SOMETHING IS
HAPPENING IN THE UNITED STATES
WITH SCHOOL SHOOTINGS.
SCHOOL SHOOTINGS WE TALKED
ABOUT WITH GOVERNOR HUCKABEE
IN 1998 JONESBORO, ARKANSAS,
EVERYBODY REMEMBERS THAT ONE.
IT FELT LIKE SOMETHING UNUSUAL
THAT WAS SHOCKING AND IN THOSE
20 YEARS, YOU KNOW, THAT HAVE
PASSED, 15 YEARS, IT SEEMS
THAT THERE'S MORE AND MORE R
PREVALENT.
THE CONVERSATION HAS TO BEGIN
ABOUT WHAT WAS HAPPENING THAT
MAKES PRIMARILY YOUNG BOYS,
THEY WERE THAT ONE IN
ARKANSAS, AND ADAM YESTERDAY
LANZA WAS 20 YEARS OLD AND
SOMETHING IS HAPPENING WITH
YOUNG MEN, YOUNG BOYS AND
SCHOOL SHOOTINGS.
>> IN THAT CASE, IN ARKANSAS,
PERHAPS PARENTING.
>> PERHAPS CULTURE.
>> AND ROD WHEELER CONTINUES
WITH US NOW.
ALI IS WRITE.
IS IT THE CULTURE, THE GUNS,
IS IT PARENTS?
WHAT DO YOU SAY.
>> I DO DON'T POLITICAL
THINGS, GUNS DON'T KILL
PEOPLE, PEOPLE KILL PEOPLE AND
KNIVES--
I DON'T THINK IT'S TIME TO
FOCUS ON THAT TYPE OF A
SITUATION.
WHAT WE NEED TO FOCUS ON IS
THE MENTAL HEALTH IN THIS
COUNTRY.
WE IN LAW ENFORCEMENT ARE
GOING TO CONTINUE TO RESPOND
AND TEACHERS ARE GOING TO
CONTINUE TO TEACH AND SCHOOLS
ARE GOING TO CONTINUE TO GO
TO--
STUDENTS ARE GOING TO CONTINUE
TO GO TO SCHOOLS.
THE SCHOOLS ARE SAFE AND
TEACHERS PREPARE FOR THESE
TYPE OF HORRIFIC EVENTS TO
GUARD AGAINST WHAT THAT SCHOOL
TEACHER DID YESTERDAY, A HERO
DEFINITELY.
I DON'T THINK IT'S APPROPRIATE
TO POINT THE FINGER RIGHT NOW
SAYING THIS IS THE CAUSE.
I THINK WHAT WE NEED TO DO IS
START ADDRESSING SOME PERSONAL
ISSUES THAT PEOPLE MAY BE
HAVING.
>> ROD, WHAT YOU'RE SAYING IS
WE HAVE TO IDENTIFY DANGEROUS
PEOPLE AND HOW DO YOU DO THAT
WITHOUT INFRINGING ON PEOPLE'S
PERSONAL RIGHTS?
>> THAT'S INTERESTING, BRIAN,
YOU ASKED ME EARLY.
AND I GET ASKED THAT A LOT.
AND SOME PEOPLE SAY, ISN'T
THAT PROFILING?
IN 2012 WE CAN'T WORRY ABOUT
THAT.
IF YOU HAVE AN INDIVIDUAL AND
THAT'S SO IMPORTANT, THAT'S
SHOWING SIGNS, THEY'RE
ISOLATED FROM EVERYBODY ELSE,
AND MAKING STRANGE COMMENTS
AND A CONNECTION WITH WEAPONS.
LOOK, DO WHAT YOU WANT TO DO,
BUT YOU HAVE TO LET SOMEBODY
KNOW THAT.
LET THE EXPERTS COME IN AND
POLICE DEPARTMENTS,
COUNSELORS, TALK WITH THE
PERSONS AND THESE ARE THE
INDIVIDUALS COMMITTING THE
ACTS AND AT THE SAME TIME WE
HAVE AN OBLIGATION TO KEEP OUR
SCHOOL SAFE AND I THINK
THEY'RE RELATIVELY SAFE, GUYS.
>> OF COURSE, OF COURSE, AND
JUST THE--
AND AN INCIDENT LIKE THIS THAT
STRIKES AT THE HEART OF THE
COUNTRIES, BECAUSE IT IS SO
UNUSUAL AND JUST WHEN YOU
THINK YOU CAN NEVER HEAR
SOMETHING MORE HORRIFYING THAN
VIRGINIA TECH, MORE THAN
COLUMBINE, THE IDEA THAT THIS
ONE IS EVEN BECAUSE OF THE--
THAT THEY WERE
KINDERGARTENERS, THEY WERE
FIVE YEARS OLD, THEY WERE SIX
YEARS OLD, SOMEHOW, A CRAZED
GUNMAN CAN FIND SOMETHING
THAT'S MORE EVIL AND HORRIBLE.
>> AND THERE'S A STORY OUT
THERE, ROD, THAT SAYS THAT
THIS YOUNG ADAM APPARENTLY
SUFFERED--
HAD SOME SORT OF PERSONALITY
DISORDER, BUT ONE OF THE
NEWSPAPERS TODAY IS SAYING
THAT HE HAD A CONDITION WHERE
HE COULD NOT FEEL PAIN.
AND THERE'S A PICTURES OF HIM
WHEN HE WAS A YOUNGER MAN.
AND IN FACT, WHEN HE WAS ON
THE BASEBALL TEAM THEY REPORT,
EVERYBODY HAD TO BE CAREFUL,
HE DIDN'T FALL BECAUSE HE
COULD GET HURT AND NOT FEEL
IT.
SO, I MEAN, YOU KNOW, THERE'S
A WHOLE BUNCH OF UNANSWERED
QUESTIONS REGARDING HIS
BACKGROUND THAT WE NEED TO
FILL IN.
ALTHOUGH AT THIS PRESS
CONFERENCE, WHICH IS GETTING,
YOU KNOW, WE WERE SUPPOSED TO
START AT 71 MINUTES AGO, THEY
STILL HAVEN'T GOTTEN THINGS
GOING AND WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF
THE DELAY, WHAT ANYTHING, ROD?
>> STEVE, I THINK WE'RE GOING
TO CONTINUE AS WE GO ALONG
WE'LL LEARN MORE ABOUT THIS
MONSTER, THIS GUY WHO
COMMITTED THIS.
WE'LL HEAR MORE ABOUT THE
PAST.
AND DON'T READ TOO MUCH INTO
THE REASON THAT THE PRESS
CONFERENCE IS DELAYED.
THEY'RE TRYING TO PROVIDE US
WITH INFORMATION THAT WE NEED
TO HAVE.
AND THE PARENTS OF THE
DECEDENTS, PROBABLY WANT TO GO
OVER ALL THE INFORMATION ABOUT
EACH PARENTS BEFORE THEY GO
OUT THERE.
AND I WOULDN'T READ TOO MUCH
IN IT.
WE'LL HEAR A LOT MORE ABOUT
SHOOTER AND HE LEFT--
AND DIDN'T HEAR IT IN THE
PRESS CONFERENCE, BUT I THINK
HE LEFT US A NOTE OR
SOMETHING.
SOME INDICATION THAT HE WAS
GOING TO DO WHAT HE DID
YESTERDAY.
THERE HAS TO BE SOMETHING.
>> AND SEEING HE HAD TO BUY
THE BODY ARMOR AND PLANNED THE
ATTACK AND THE CLASSROOM AND
NO ONE QUESTIONED HIS
INTELLECT.
PEOPLE ARE SAYING, HE KNEW HE
GREW UP IN THE AREA AND MOM
POSSIBLY WORKED AT THE SCHOOL.
AND THERE IS ANOTHER REPORT
UNCONFIRMED AND RELAYED FROM
LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS
UNDER THE AGREEMENT OF STAYING
ANONYMOUS THAT HE MIGHT HAVE
GONE TO THAT SCHOOL AS A
STUDENT.
SO, MAYBE THAT SOMETHING TO DO
WITH IT AND SOMETHING ELSE
STRUCK ME WHEN YOU WERE
ANSWERING THAT QUESTION, ROD,
WHEN HE WAS IN THE SYSTEM AS A
KID HE WAS IN CONTROL AND
DIDN'T KILL ANYBODY.
AND WHEN YOU'RE AN ADULT YOU
GET TO GO ON YOUR OWN AND GET
MORTGAGES AND NOT TO BE
ACCOUNTABLE AND GETS YOUR OWN
APARTMENT AND WHEN YOU GET
AWAY FROM THAT SUPERVISION IS
WHEN THE DANGER KICKS IN.
>> EXACTLY.
WELL, MAYBE, BRIAN, THAT'S THE
REASON HE KILLED HIS MOTHER.
AND DR. KEITH ABLOW AND
THEY'RE THE ONES THAT FIGURE
THAT STUFF OUT.
ALL WE CAN DO IS FIGURE OUT
HOW TO REMAIN SAFE GOING
FORWARD AND WE HAVE TO LOOK AT
EACH CHILD'S LIFE THAT'S TAKEN
AND WE'RE GOING TO CONTINUE TO
LIVE THAT CHILD'S LIFE FOR
THEM SO ANOTHER CHILD COULDN'T
BE HARMED GOING FORWARD.
>> WE THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR
JOINING US.
WE'VE BEEN LOOKING FOR THE
LAST HOUR AT 15 MINUTES AT THE
PRESS CONFERENCE THAT'S
SUPPOSED TO TAKE PLACE.
WE STILL HAVEN'T GOTTEN THE
TWO MINUTE WARNING SO WE'RE
GOING TO STEP ASIDE AND YOU'LL
SEE ALL OF IT IN ITS ENTIRETY
HERE ON THE FOX NEWS CHANNEL.
>> Alisyn: AND AS DR. BODDEN
SAYS, FORENSIC PATHOLOGIST CAN
TELL A LOT SO HE'LL JOIN US
NEXT.
I HAD ENOUGH OF FEELING
EMBARRASSED ABOUT MY SKIN.
[ Designer ]
ENOUGH OF JUST COVERING UP
MY MODERATE TO SEVERE
PLAQUE PSORIASIS.
I DECIDED ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
♪
[ Spa Lady ]
I STARTED ENBREL.
IT'S CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO PROVIDE CLEARER SKIN.
[ RV Guy ] ENBREL MAY NOT WORK
FOR EVERYONE --
AND MAY NOT CLEAR YOU
COMPLETELY,
BUT FOR MANY, IT GETS SKIN
CLEARER FAST, WITHIN 2 MONTHS,
AND KEEPS IT CLEARER
UP TO 9 MONTHS.
[ Male Announcer ]
BECAUSE ENBREL®, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL,
EVENTS INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS, LYMPHOMA,
OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING ENBREL,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START ENBREL IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON ENBREL, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING,
OR PALENESS.
IF YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH, ASK
YOUR DERMATOLOGIST ABOUT ENBREL.
AWW MAN.
[ Male Announcer ] RETURNS
ARE EASY WITH FREE PICKUP
FROM THE U.S. POSTAL SERVICE.
WE'LL EVEN DROP OFF BOXES
IF YOU NEED THEM.
VISIT USPS.COM
PAY, PRINT,
AND HAVE IT PICKED UP FOR FREE.
ANY TIME OF YEAR.
♪
NICE SWEATER.
THANK YOU.
♪
>>
>>  WELCOME BACK EVERYONE,
WE'RE STILL AWAITING A LIVE
PRESS CONFERENCE OUT OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, IT LOOKS
LIKE THERE MAY BE SOME
MOVEMENT THERE.
OBVIOUSLY, THIS IS WHERE
POLICE WILL COME AND GIVE US
ANY NEW DETAILS THEY'VE BEEN
ABLE TO UNEARTH ABOUT THE
SHOOTER IN THIS TRAGEDY, AS
WELL AS THE VICTIMS AND 26
LIVES LOST AT THIS SCHOOL,
INCLUDING 20 YOUNG CHILDREN.
>> Brian: WE'LL GO THERE AS
SOON AS IT STARTS EVEN IF IT
MEANS STOPPING MID SENTENCE OR
MID BREAK.
DR. BADEN, THEY'VE MOVED THE
BODIES OUT.
AND WHEN THE PRESS WENT AWAY,
THE BODIES MOVED OUT AND FOR
THE FAMILIES.
WHAT DOES IT MEAN.
>> THE SCHOOL IS LOCKED DOWN
AND THE INVESTIGATORS CAN GO
THROUGHOUT THE SCHOOL AND DO
ALL THEY HAVE TO DO AND TAKE A
FEW MORE DAYS TO BE ABLE TO
DOCUMENT EVERYTHING, AND
MEANWHILE, THE FAMILIES KNOW
THAT THEIR LOVED ONES HAVE
BEEN IDENTIFIED.
THEY'VE IDENTIFIED THEM AND
PROBABLY MOVED THEM OUT TO THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER'S OFFICE IN
FARMINGTON, CONNECTICUT, AND
THE BODIES WILL BE RELEASED
FROM THERE WHEN THEY'RE
FINISHED WITH WHATEVER
ADDITIONAL HAS TO BE DONE.
>> Steve: IT MUST HAVE BEEN
EXCRUCIATING FOR 20 SETS OF
PARENTS TO HAVE WAITED OUTSIDE
AT THAT SCHOOL FOR PRACTICALLY
24 HOURS, IF THE BODIES WERE
MOVED LAST NIGHT.
>> IN THE FIREHOUSE WHERE THEY
WERE AMASSING AND FOR THEM,
COME ON, WE KNOW MY CHILD IS
DEAD, WHY DO I HAVE TO WAIT.
>> WELL, THEY HAVE TO IDENTIFY
EACH CHILD TO MAKE SURE THE
WRONG CHILD DOESN'T GO AND NOW
THAT THAT'S BEEN DONE, THEY'LL
SOON HAVE THE BODIES BECAUSE
THE BODIES HAVE TO BE
EXAMINED.
>> AND THE MEDICAL EXAMINER?
>> AND THAT WILL BE WHERE
THEY'D BE AND RELEASED FROM
THERE IS THE USUAL WAY IT'S
DONE, UNLESS THEY HAD X-RAY
FACILITIES BROUGHT DOWN TO THE
SCHOOL BECAUSE THEY WANT TO
REMOVE THE BULLETS.
>> Alisyn: DR. BADEN,
EVERYTHING YOU'RE TALKING
ABOUT IS SO TECHNICAL AND IT'S
SO, KIND OF CLINICAL AND
MEDICAL, I KNOW THAT'S YOUR
JOB, BUT THIS IS ABOUT THE
HEART BREAK OF PARENTS AND
PARTICULARLY GIVEN THAT WE
KNOW WHO THE SHOOTER WAS,
THERE'S NOT GOING TO BE A
TRIAL FOR THE SHOOTER BECAUSE
HE TOOK HIS OWN LIFE.
YOU HAVE POINTED OUT THAT
THERE WILL STILL BE TRIALS
BECAUSE YOU PREDICT, HAVING
BEEN AROUND THINGS LIKE THIS
BEFORE.
>> RIGHT.
>> Alisyn: THAT THERE WILL BE
LAWSUITS, BUT ALSO SOUNDS LIKE
THE SCHOOL DID EVERYTHING
RIGHT.
THEY DID HAVE SECURITY IN
PLACE AND DID DO SAFETY DRILLS
AND THE PRINCIPAL DID THE
RIGHT THING.
HOW, SOMETIMES HORRIBLE THINGS
HAPPEN AND THERE'S NO LAWSUIT
THAT'S GOING TO FIX IT.
>> THAT'S RIGHT, BUT AT THE
SAME TIME THE POLICE AND THE
MEDICAL EXAMINERS HAVE A
CERTAIN PROTOCOL THEY HAVE TO
DOCUMENT BECAUSE THEY KNOW A
YEAR, TWO, THREE YEARS FROM
NOW, ISSUES CAN COME UP AND IF
THEY HAVEN'T MADE THE
DOCUMENTATION IT'S GOING TO BE
WORSE FOR THE FAMILIES HAVING
TO LIVE THROUGH IT AGAIN,
HAVING TO EXHUME A BODY, FOR
EXAMPLE, WOULD BE TERRIBLE SO
THEY HAVE TO GET EVERYTHING
FROM THE REMAINS AS MUCH AS
POSSIBLE AND THEN RELEASE THE
BODY.
THE WAY THEY'RE DOING IT,
THEY'RE DOING IT VERY QUICKLY
AND HOPEFULLY, BOY MONDAY AND
TUESDAY THERE'LL BE SOME--
>> ISSUES.
>> BODIES RELEASED.
>> Brian: AND DO YOU HAVE TO
BRING THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT
INTO THIS?
YOU SAID FARMINGTON IS WHERE
THEY'RE GOING IN CONNECTICUT.
ARE THEY GOING TO NEED SOME
HELP?
>> NO, NO, THE MEDICAL
EXAMINERS ARE.
>> Brian: THEY HAVE HANDLE 26,
28 PEOPLE?
>> YES, THEY CAN HANDLE IT.
THE ISSUE OF HOMICIDE TO DO AT
THE SCHOOL, THEN THEY MIGHT
NEED EQUIPMENT, BUT THEY WILL
EVERYTHING IN CONNECTICUT AS I
SAID.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER, DR. KARR
VER IS A VERY COMPETENT GUY.
>> Steve: WE'RE HOPING TO HEAR
MORE DETAILS, THE PRESS
CONFERENCE WE'RE TOLD IS GOING
TO START MOMENTARILY.
>> Alisyn: AFTER THIS
UNSPEAKABLE TRAGEDY WHAT, WILL
HAPPEN NEXT IN NEWTOWN?
WE'LL CHECK WITH PETER
JOHNSON, HE'S ON THE GROUND
AND TALKING TO PEOPLE THERE.
>> AND FOR SOME OF THEM--
initiated.
Neural speeds
increasing to 4G LTE.
Brain upgrading to a quad-core
processor.
Predictive intelligence
with Google Now complete.
Introducing DROID DNA by HTC.
It's not an upgrade
to your phone.
It's an upgrade to yourself.
>>  ALL RIGHT.
WELCOME BACK, EVERYONE, WE ARE
HE AWAITING THIS PRESS
CONFERENCE LIVE OUT OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE EXPECT TO LEARN NEW DETAILS
ABOUT THIS HORRIFIC TRAGEDY
THAT TOOK THE LIVES OF 26
PEOPLE, INCLUDING 20 CHILDREN
AT THIS SCHOOL YESTERDAY.
>> AND WE'RE GOING TO GO TO
THAT PRESSER AS SOON AS IT
STARTS, WHENEVER IT STARTS AT
ANY MOMENT, BUT UNTIL THEN,
NEWTOWN, COMING TOGETHER.
LAST NIGHT TO REMEMBER THE
LIVES THAT WERE LOST THERE.
THE YOUNG LIVES AS WELL AS THE
GROWN-UPS SAID THEY TRIED TO
FIND COMFORT IN FAITH AND IN
GOD AND FOR THAT STORY WE NOW
GO TO PETER JOHNSON, JR. WHO
IS LIVE THERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, PETER GOOD
MORNING.
>> GOOD MORNING, IT WAS A SAD
BEAUTIFUL SUNRISE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
FROM THE PESHPESH PERISH, AND
TEARS IN PEOPLE'S EYES AND MY
DAUGHTER AND I LET CANDLES FOR
THE ADULTS AND LIVES LOST IN
THIS TOWN.
OUR GUEST IS THE MONSIGNOR
WHITE.
>> GOOD MORNING.
>> TELL US ABOUT THE PAIN IN
THE TOWN, ONE YOUNG CHILDREN
WAS TO BE AN ANGEL, AT ST.
LIMA AND ANOTHER YOU HAD TO
BREAK HIS SISTER DIED YOU HAD
TO BREAK THE NEWS AND TELL US
WHAT THE PARISHIONERS ARE
FEELING ON THIS DAY?
>> THIS COMMUNITY IS AN
INCREDIBLE COMMUNITY AND
PEOPLE CHOOSE TO LIVE HERE
IT'S ALL ABOUT FAMILIES AND
BEING TOGETHER AND SUPPORTING
EACH OTHER.
THIS HAS JUST BROKEN THE HEART
OF THE TOWN TO SEE THE 20
INCIDENT CHILDREN AND ADULTS
SENSELESSLY TAKEN FROM US.
THE SPIRIT IN THIS TOWN IS
VERY, VERY HEAVY AND THE
REALITY OF THIS EVENT IS
REALLY STARTING TO SETTLE IN.
AND HAVING BEEN WITH MANY OF
THE FAMILIES THROUGHOUT THE
DAY AND EARLY THIS MORNING,
YOU REALIZE THAT LIFE HAS
CHANGED FOREVER.
AND YOU HOPE THAT OUT OF ALL
OF THIS, THIS BAD, SOME KIND
OF GOODWILL COME.
AND YOU KNOW, PRAY GOD WITH
FAITH AND WITH HOPE BE ABLE TO
SUPPORT AND SUSTAIN EACH
OTHER.
>> IN TERMS OF FAITH AND HOPE,
WHAT DO YOU TELL -- WHAT DID
YOU TELL A LITTLE BOY ABOUT
THE DEATH OF HIS SISTER AT THE
HANDS OF A MADMAN?
>> YOU KNOW, I STARTED TALKING
WITH HIM AND HE SAID TO ME,
YOU KNOW, I DON'T HAVE ANYBODY
TO PLAY WITH ANYMORE, YOU'VE
LOST MY BEST FRIEND.
AND I SAID TO HIM, YOU KNOW,
THAT GOD'S GOING TO SEND YOU
SOME WONDERFUL NEW FRIENDS.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE AFRAID
AND YOU'LL ALWAYS HAVE YOUR
SISTER IN YOUR HEART AND I
SAID TO HIM, YOU DON'T HAVE TO
WORRY BECAUSE SHE'S VERY SAFE
BECAUSE SHE'S WITH GOD AND WE
TALKED A LITTLE ABOUT WHAT
HEAVEN WAS LIKE, AND HE
REALIZED THAT SHE WAS GOING TO
BE HAPPEN, IF A SHE WAS GOING
TO BE SAFE, BUT IT WAS SHORTLY
AFTER THIS, THAT HE BROKE DOWN
INTO TEARS.
>> Reporter:  AND IT'S ABOUT
SAFETY AND LOVE AND I KNOW
YOU'VE DECIDED AND PARISH HAS
DECIDED TO GO FORWARD WITH A
LIVE NATIVITY PAGEANT AND AT
5:30, A MAN WILL COME INTO THE
CHURCH AND STAY THAT THERE IS
A STAR OVER THE STABLE AND THE
CHURCH WILL PROCEED OUT TO THE
STABLE TO A LIVE NATIVITY
SCENE AND THIS TOWN WAS SO
PROUD THEY WERE GETTING A
CAMEL FOR THE NATIVITY SCENE
AND LOOK AT THE BABY JESUS,
WHEN YOUR PARISHIONERS LOOK AT
THE BABY JESUS IN TKRESH.
WHAT DOES IT SAY.
>> WE'RE NOT JUST LOOKING FOR
ONE STAR, WE'LL LOOK FOR 20
STARS AND THE LIGHT SHINING
OVER CHRIST IS GOING TO SHINE
OVER THE FAMILY AS WELL.
AND THESE CHILDREN ARE ANGELS
NOW.
WHEN THEY REFLECT ON THE
CHRIST CHILD BORN HE DID BRING
US HOPE IN THE WORST TIMES
HE'S EVER PRESENT TO US AND
I'M HOPING THE MESSAGE PEOPLE
CAN TAKE TONIGHT, THERE'S
STILL A REASON TO HOPE AND
LIVE ON AND FAMILIES OF OTHER
CHILDREN THAT THEY HAVE TO
RAISE AND HOPING THAT THE
STRENGTH THAT COMES FROM THE
CHRIST CHILD WILL BE FOR THESE
FAMILIES AND WITH THESE
PARENTS.
>> Reporter:  A TEACHER SAID
YESTERDAY, ONE OF THE CHILDREN
SAID AS SHE WAS PROTECTING
THEM FROM WHAT SHE BELIEVED TO
BE CERTAIN DEATH, I DON'T WANT
TO DIE, I JUST WANT TO HAVE
CHRISTMAS.
SO THE INNOCENCE OF THESE
CHILDREN ARE ARTICULATED IN
THAT STATEMENT.
THIS IS A TOUGH THING FOR YOU
AND YOU'RE A STRONG MAN AND
YOU'RE ONE OF THE GREAT
PRIESTS, ACCORDING TO MY
FRIEND CARDINAL EGAN IN THE
STATE OF CONNECTICUT WHO IS
THE BISHOP HERE.
HOW DO YOU STAY STRONG AND HOW
DO YOU GET THE MESSAGE OUT IN
A WAY THAT HELPS PEOPLE?
>> YOU KNOW, I'M TAKING A LOT
OF STRENGTH FROM THESE
PARENTS.
YOU KNOW, IF--
AS I WAS WEARING THEM SIT
THERE YESTERDAY AND THEY WERE
BREAKING DOWN AND HORRIBLE
MOMENTS THERE WAS SUCH A BOND
AND AFFECTION AND LOVE FOR THE
CHILDREN AND EACH OTHER AND
YOU DRAW A LOT OF STRENGTH
FROM THAT, EVEN IN THEIR LIVES
OF GREATEST WEAKNESS AND WHAT
ST. PAUL TELLS US, THE
WEAKNESS AND FIND OUR
STRENGTH.
MY FAITH WAS NOT SHAKEN BY
THIS.
MY FAITH IN HUMANITY IS ALWAYS
SHAKEN WHEN THINGS LIKE THIS
HAPPEN AND THE CHILDREN CAN'T
TRUST BEING IN A PLACE SAFE
AND HAPPY AND SOMEONE WHO HAS
SEVERE ISSUES OF THIS MAN AND
COME IN AND TAKE THAT AWAY
FROM THEM.
WE'RE VERY WORRIED ABOUT THE
CHILDREN'S FEARS AND ANXIETIES
AFTER YESTERDAY, BUT HOPED
CHRISTMAS SEASON WILL RENEW
SOME OF THAT AND AFTER THEY
RETURN TO SCHOOL THEY WILL HE'
FEEL BETTER AND A LITTLE BIT
SAFER.
>> Reporter:  WELL, THIS
COMMUNITY IS IN GOOD HANDS
WOULD YOU.
AND ON BEHALF OF AMERICA,
THANK YOU FOR DOING WHAT
YOU'RE DOING AND ALL WISH TO
THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN, A
FEELING SAFE AND AT PEACE IN
THIS SEASON.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH MONSIGNOR,
YOU KNOW, MARTIN LUTHER KING
SAID, DEATH IS NOT ONE VALLEY,
BUT SOME OF THE PEOPLE I SPOKE
TO IN NEWTOWN THIS MORNING,
BUT WE CAN HOPE AGAINST HOPE
THAT THE LIGHT OF CHRISTMAS
SIGNS THROUGH ON THIS
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE TOWN THAT WAS
ATTACKED BY PAIN AND FEARS AND
TRAGEDY ON THIS DAY.
BACK TO YOU GUYS IN THE
STUDIO.
>> Steve: ALL RIGHT.
PETER MONSIGNOR, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
TEN DAYS UNTIL CHRISTMAS.
>> Alisyn: WELL, WE HAVE BRAND
NEW INFORMATION ABOUT THE
SHOOTER AND HIS CHIRELATIONSHIP
WITH HIS BROTHER AND FAMILY
AND EXPLORE BUSINEHIS BACKGROUN
WHEN WE COME BACK.
>>  ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE WAITING A LIVE PRESS
CONFERENCE AT NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, SCHEDULED TORE
EIGHT O'CLOCK AND LEARNING A
BRAND NEW START TIME.
>> Steve: WE HOPE IT STARTS
WITHIN THE NEXT HALF HOUR AND
WE'LL BRING IT TO YOU LIVE
WHENEVER IT DOES HAPPEN.
>> Alisyn: FIRST WE WANT TO GO
TO PETER DOOCY LIVE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT ALL NIGHT
AND BRAND NEW INFORMATION,
PETER, WHAT HAVE YOU FOUND
OUT.
>> Reporter:  ALISYN, AGAIN
YOU MENTIONED THAT THE PRESS
CONFERENCE HAS BEEN DELAYED BY
ABOUT AN HOUR AND A HALF, BUT
THE LAST WE WERE ABLE TO TALK
TO SOMEONE FROM THE LOCAL
POLICE DEPARTMENT, THEY TOLD
US AS OF ABOUT 7:30 THIS
MORNING, THAT SOME OF THE
BODIES HAD BEEN REMOVED FROM
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
AND THAT SOME OF THE BODIES
HAD NOT.
I MENTIONED EARLIER THAT THERE
WAS A MAKESHIFT MORGUE BUILT
SOMEWHERE INSIDE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY, WHERE AUTHORITIES
WENT IT TAKE PHOTOGRAPHS OF
THE YOUNG VICTIMS, TO SHOW THE
PHOTOGRAPHS TO THE PARENTS,
FOR POSITIVE IDENTIFICATION
AND WE HEARD, AGAIN, THE LAST
OFFICIAL WORD THAT WE HAD FROM
THE POLICE TWO HOURS AGO WAS
THAT SOME OF THE BODIES STILL
WERE INSIDE OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
NOW, SOMETHING ELSE THAT WE
HEARD THAT IS NEW, THAT SOME
EVIDENCE IS INSIDE THE SCHOOL
AND SOME EVIDENCE IS OUTSIDE
AND WE'RE TOLD THAT SOME OF
THE INSIDE EVIDENCE INCLUDES
FIREARMS IN ADDITION TO THE
THREE THAT WE KNEW ABOUT
YESTERDAY.
SO, WE KNEW THAT HE HAD TWO
PISTOLS AND A RIFLE THAT THEY
FOUND IN HIS CAR, WE'RE NOW
TOLD THERE WERE ADDITIONAL
FIREARMS FOUND ON SCHOOL
GROUNDS AND WE DON'T KNOW WHEN
AND AS FOR THE EVIDENCE
OUTSIDE, WE'RE TOLD THE
VEHICLES AND THAT THE VEHICLES
INCLUDE THE SUSPECT'S
VEHICLES, SO, OBVIOUSLY, THE
SUSPECT VEHICLES AND MAYBE
SOME OF THE VICTIMS VEHICLES,
BUT WE'VE ALSO BEEN TOLD BY
SOME NEIGHBORS WHO HEARD THE
GUNSHOTS AND HEADED OVER
THERE, THEIR CARS ARE STUCK IN
THE AREA THAT'S LOCKED DOWN
AND JUST TRYING TO SORT OUT
WHOSE CAR GOES WHERE AND IF
THE PEOPLE WHO THE CAR OWNERS
SURVIVED YESTERDAY'S ATTACK.
AUTHORITIES ALSO ARE NOW
SAYING NA IT APPEARS THAT ADAM
LANZA SHOT OUT THE GLASS NEXT
TO THE FRONT DOOR OF THE
SCHOOL, TO GAIN ENTRY.
NG A LOT ABOUT
HOW SECURE THE SCHOOL WAS.
I TALKED TO ANOTHER TEACHER
FROM THE DISTRICT, NOT FROM
THIS SPECIFIC SCHOOL, BUT
SOMEBODY WHO IS VERY, VERY
FAMILIAR WITH THE SECURITY
PROTOCOL AND SHE SAID AS SOON
AS SCHOOL STARTS IF ANYBODY
WANTS TO GET IN, INCLUDING
PARENTS OR SIBLINGS, THEY,
SINCE ALL THE DOORS ARE
LOCKED, THEY NEED TO BASICALLY
WAVE TO A CAMERA THAT BEAMS A
PICTURE INTO THE FRONT OFFICE
AND THEN SOMEONE IN THE FRONT
OFFICE NEEDS TO BUZZ THAT
PERSON IN AND THEN THAT PERSON
NEEDS TO GO RIGHT TO THE FRONT
OFFICE.
WE'RE HEARING NOW THAT
AUTHORITIES SAY IT APPEARS
THIS GUNMAN SHOT OUT THAT
GLASS.
WE ALSO TALKED TO A LIBRARY
CLERK.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE SOME NEW
SOUND AT THE TOP OF THE TEN
O'CLOCK HOUR, SHE SAID, SHE
WAS WITH SOME FOURTH GRADERS
IN THE BACK OF THE SCHOOL, BUT
SHE SAID HER UNDERSTANDING IS
THAT THE GUNMAN ENTERED THE
SCHOOL AND THEN SKIPPED THE
FIRST CLASSROOM AND THEN DID
MOST OF HIS SHOOTING IN THE
TWO CLASSROOMS NEXT TO THE
FIRST ONE.
SO WENT RIGHT PAST THE FIRST
ONE FOR SOME REASON ACCORDING
TO THIS LIBRARY CLERK, HER
NAME IS MARY ANNE JACOB AND
JUST DID THE SHOOTING IN THE
SECOND TWO CLASSROOMS, WE ALSO
ARE HEARING FROM HER THAT WHEN
THEY EVACUATED THE STUDENTS TO
THE FIREHOUSE, THEY ALL LINED
UP AND THEY ALL LINED UP BY
GRADE AND BEHIND THEIR
TEACHERS SO THEY COULD DO A
HEAD COUNT AND IT WAS THEN
THAT THE TEACHERS REALIZED
THAT ABOUT 10:30, ELEVEN
O'CLOCK IN THE MORNING THAT
TWO ENTIRE FIRST GRADE CLASSES
WERE MISSING.
AND THIS LIBRARY CLERK, MARY
ANNE SAYS THAT THEY WERE AT
THE FIREHOUSE, WHICH IS WHERE
THE FAMILIES CAME TO CLAIM
THEIR CHILDREN AND REALIZED
WHEN THEY WERE LINING UP BY
GRADE BEHIND THEIR TEACHERS
THAT TWO ENTIRE FIRST GRADE
CLASSES WERE NOT ACCOUNTED FOR
EXCEPT FOR A FEW KIDS, AGAIN,
WE'RE EXPECTING TO HEAR MORE
INFORMATION WHENEVER THIS
PRESS CONFERENCE STARTS
HOPEFULLY IN THE NEXT FEW
MINUTES, BACK TO YOU.
>> Brian: THANKS A LOT, PETER.
YOU WONDER THE ROLE, DID HE IN
FACT ATTEND THIS SCHOOL A
GRUDGE THAT THIS GUY IN HIS
TWISTED MIND WAS TRYING TO
AVENGE BY DOING THIS OR
PSYCHOTIC DRUGS PLAYING A ROLE
IN THIS.
CERTAINLY, WE STILL DON'T KNOW
A LOT ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED AT
THE TIME OF THE SHOOTING, BUT
WE'RE FINDING OUT MORE.
>> Alisyn: MEANWHILE, ONE OF
THE SOURCES IS THE LIBRARY
CLERK THAT PETER JUST
MENTIONED, MARY ANNE JACOB AND
HE SHE WAS INSIDE THE SCHOOL
THE INTERCOM BUTTON, PA SYSTEM
WAS PRESSED AND ALERTED
TEACHERS SOMETHING WAS
TERRIBLY WRONG IN THE FRONT
OFFICE, LET'S LISTEN TO HER.
>> THE INTERCOM WENT OFF AS IF
THEY WERE GOING TO MAKE AN
ANNOUNCEMENT AND WE HEARD SOME
NOISES AND STUFF AND I THOUGHT
SOMEBODY HAD HIT THE BUTTON BY
MISTAKE AND THEY WERE IN THE
OFFICE AND I CALLED DOWN
THERE, AND ONE OF THE
SECRETARIES ANSWERED THE PHONE
AND SAID THERE WAS A SHOOTING
AND THEN YOU BECOME AWARE WE
STARTED HEARING THE GUNSHOTS,
SO I YELLED LOCKDOWN TO THE
GROUP IN OUR ROOM AND RAN
ACROSS THE HALL.
>> SO IT SOUNDS LIKE THAT
INTERCOM DID SAVE SOME LIVES
BECAUSE PEOPLE STARTED TO LOCK
THEIR DOORS.
AND WITH PETER'S INFORMATION,
EARLIER THIS MORNING WE LOOKED
IN THE NEW YORK TIMES, IT SAYS
THAT THE PRINCIPAL BUZZED ADAM
LANZA IN, NOT THE CASE, HE
SHOT HIS WAY IN BY BREAKING
THE WINDOW AND MORE THAN THREE
GUNS WE KNEW OF.
IT'S INTERESTING WE KNOW THE
GUNS BELONGED TO HIS MOTHER
AND WE DON'T KNOW HIS
EXPERIENCE WITH A GUN.
AND IF HE WENT TO A PISTOL
RANGE OR ANYTHING LIKE THAT.
AND A BIG GAMER AND APPARENTLY
VERY ACCURATE.
IS THERE A CONNECTION?
NO DOUBT PEOPLE ARE GOING TO
BE CALLING FOR A REVIEW OF
VIDEO GAME RATINGS, NOW.
>> BUT HE'S 20 YEARS OLD.
>> EXACTLY.
>> Brian: WE'RE GETTING NEW
INFORMATION ABOUT ADAM LANZA'S
BROTHER, HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY,
AND HE'S GETTING HAMMER, AND A
LOT OF PEOPLE THOUGHT
ORIGINALLY, ANNA KOOIMAN, THAT
HE WAS THE KILLER.
>> Reporter:  GOOD MORNING TO
EVERYBODY AT HOME.
WE'RE HEARING THAT THE LAST
SEVERAL YEARS WERE VERY ROCKY
FOR THE ALLEGED SHOOTER,
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA.
BACK IN 2006 HIS BROTHER RYAN
LANZA, 24 YEARS OLD WHO LIVES
IN THIS APARTMENT BUILDING
HERE IN HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY,
WENT OFF TO COLLEGE WHILE
THEIR PARENTS' MARRIAGE WAS IN
SHAMBLES, ENDED IN 2008.
ALTHOUGH RYAN IS NOT A
SUSPECT.
HIS HOME WAS SEARCHED
YESTERDAY, ALONG WITH COMPUTER
AND PHONE RECORDS.
THERE WAS SOME CONFUSION AS TO
HIS IDENTITY, OR AS TO THE
IDENTITY OF THE SHOOTER,
THAT'S BECAUSE ADAM LANZA WAS
CARRYING THE I.D. OF RYAN
LANZA.
WE CAN ONLY TELL YOU THAT THE
FBI SAYS THEY QUESTIONED THE
FATHER, THEY QUESTIONED RYAN
AND THEY'RE SAID TO BE IN
CONNECTICUT NOW, THEY WERE
VERY COOPERATIVE AND THAT'S
PRETTY MUCH THE LATEST HERE,
AS FAR AS WHAT THEY MENTIONED
TO THE AUTHORITIES ABOUT HIS
DEMEANOR, THEY SAID THAT HE
HAD A PERSONALITY DISORDER OF
SOME SORT, WAS AUTISTIC, AND
RYAN ALSO TOLD US HE HAD NOT
SPOKEN WITH ADAM SINCE 2010.
ON HIS FACEBOOK PAGE WERE YOU
TALKING ABOUT THAT, BRIAN.
HE SAID I WAS AT WORK, IT
WASN'T ME.
YOU CAN JUST REALLY IMAGINE
WHAT HE WAS GOING THROUGH,
WHEN PEOPLE WERE THINKING HE
WAS A MASS MURDERER.
BACK TO YOU.
>> Brian: ANNA KOOIMAN OUT IN
THE FIELD, THANK YOU SO MUCH,
FINDING OUT MORE ABOUT THE THE
FAMILY THE LANZAS.
>> Steve: IT'S INTERESTING THE
BROTHERS HADN'T APPARENTLY
SPOKEN IN TWO YEARS.
>> AND SOMETHING WAS GOING ON
WITH ADAM.
AND TALKING ABOUT HOW TO
EXPLAIN THIS TO YOUR CHILDREN,
IF THEY HAPPENED TO HEAR ABOUT
IT OR SEEN IT IN A NEWSPAPER
OR TELEVISION, AND HOW DO YOU
TELL THEM THAT THINGS LIKE
THIS EXIST.
AND SURVIVAL SKILLS, WHAT AGE
IS APPROPRIATE NEXT.
>>  TWO PAST THE BUILDING,
PAST THE GYM.
>>  ALL RIGHT.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
THOUGHT THEY WERE DOING
EVERYTHING RIGHT AND A NEW
SECURITY SYSTEM AND THEY
LOCKED THE FRONT DOORS
REQUIRING VISITORS TO GET
INSIDE AFTER SCHOOL STARTS AND
TRAGICALLY NOT ENOUGH FOR THE
26 PEOPLE WHO LOST THEIR
LIVES.
SO, WHAT ELSE CAN SCHOOLS DO
TO PREPARE AND PROTECT
THEMSELVES FOR A MASS SHOOTING
SCENARIO LIKE THIS.
>> Alisyn: A FORMER N.Y.P.D.
DETECTIVE AND A SECURITY
EXPERT.
THANKS SO MUCH FOR STICKING
AROUND WITH US.
OF COURSE, YOUR PERSPECTIVE ON
THIS IS AS A SECURITY EXPERT.
WE'VE HEARD OTHERS COME ON AND
SAY, THIS IS VERY RARE, YOU
SHOULDN'T HAVE YOUR KIDS
OBSESS ABOUT THIS.
THIS WILL ONLY MAKE YOUR KIDS
NERVOUS.
YOU HAVE A DIFFERENT TAKE ON
THAT AND YOU THINK YOU SHOULD
PREPARE YOUR KIDS FOR AN
EMERGENCY DRILL.
HOW DO YOU DO THAT?
>> EXACTLY.
AND YOU KNOW, AND WHEN I GREW
UP AS A LITTLE KID, I WAS
PLAYING SHOOT-EM-UP BANG-BANG
COWBOYS IN THE PARK EVERY
NIGHT.
THE KIDS AREN'T DOING THAT.
THEY'RE OUT THERE PLAYING THE
VIDEO GAMES AND THINGS LIKE
THAT.
IF I WAS FIVE, SIX YEARS OLD,
I WOULD HAVE KNOWN A LITTLE
HOW TO REACT HOW THIS
HAPPENED.
I WOULD HIT THE DECK BECAUSE I
WATCHED ON THE TV SHOWS I
WATCHED AS A KID.
BUT YOU KNOW, THE PROBLEM HERE
IS THAT IT LOOKS LIKE THIS
SCHOOL WAS VERY PREPARED.
ALL RIGHT.
IT LOOKS LIKE--
>> DO YOU LIKE THE SYSTEM, DO
YOU LIKE THE SYSTEM?
>> I LIKE THE SYSTEM.
COULD IT BE IMPROVED ON?
ANYTHING COULD BE IMPROVED ON.
WHEN IT COMES TO ME I'M
LOOKING AT THE BEST CASE
SCENARIO FOR YOU, THESE ARE
THE BEST THINGS THAT WE CAN
DO.
THIS IS WHAT IT'S GOING TO
COST YOU AND THEN LOOK AT
WHAT'S COST EFFECTIVE FOR YOU.
>> Steve: THE NEW NEWS THIS
MORNING IN THE LAST HOUR OR SO
IS THE FACT THAT THIS GUY, YOU
KNOW, HE SHOT HIS WAY IN.
>> RIGHT.
>> Steve: HE WASN'T BUZZED IN.
HE SHOT THROUGH THE GLASS AND
SOMEHOW OPENED THE DOOR.
IT'S HARD TO HARDEN THE ENTIRE
SCHOOL.
>> THEY CAN'T PROTECT THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
100%, AND SO WE CAN'T PROTECT
THE SCHOOL 100%, THERE'S WAYS
TO SLOW THE SHOOTER DOWN FOR
THE POLICE RESPONSE.
>> Alisyn: HOW YOUNG IS TOO
YOUNG FOR KIDS IN YOUR MIND?
CAN YOU TEACH A FIVE,
SIX-YEAR-OLD WHAT TO DO IN AN
ACTIVE SHOOTER.
>> SURE, MAKE IT A GAME.
WHEN I WAS GROWING UP,
KINDERGARTENER, THERE WAS A
SOVIET THREAT.
>> DUCK AND COVER.
>> UNDER A DESK OR HIDE LIKE
THIS UP AGAINST THE WALL.
YOU CAN MAKE IT A GAME FOR THE
KIDS AND THEY LOVE TO PLAY
GAMES AND RELATE TO SOMETHING
LIKE THIS IF IT HAPPENS.
>> YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT
SECURING THE DOOR AND MAYBE
HAVING A DEAD BOLT SO PEEFR
SCHOOL HAS AN ABILITY WHEN THE
ALARM GOES OFF.
>> RIGHT.
>> THEY CAN QUICKLY DEAD BOLT
THE DOOR AND SLOW DOWN THE
GUY.
THE BIG QUESTION PEOPLE HAVE
NOW, WRITING AND TWEETING US,
WOULD IT BE BET ARE TO HAVE
SOMEBODY AT THAT DOOR ARMED IN
A SMALL COMMUNITY LIKE
NEWTOWN?
>> AGAIN, BEST CASE SCENARIO,
I SAY YES, NOW WHY?
BECAUSE IT'S OUR CHILDREN AND
NOT GOING TO--
LISTEN, WE'VE GOT POLICE
OFFICERS, SECURITY PEOPLE OUT
ON THE STREET EVERY DAY, ALL
OVER THIS COUNTRY, THAT ARE
ARMED.
AND SOME PEOPLE ARE AFRAID
THAT EVEN THEY'RE ARMED.
ALL RIGHT?
AND NOTHING BAD HAPPENS.
EVERY ONCE IN A WHILE WE HAVE
SOME KIND AFTER PROBLEM, ALL
RIGHT?
BUT I PERSONALLY DON'T THINK
THERE'S ANYTHING WRONG WITH
HAVING AN ARMED GUARD AND--
>> AND PERHAPS THE LOCAL
POLICE FORCE.
>> RIGHT, OR A LOCAL POLICE
FORCE OR SOMEBODY WHO IS
PROFESSIONAL TRAINED.
I WOULD NOT HAVE THEM IN
UNIFORM, ALL RIGHT?
>> ALL RIGHT.
AND HARRY, THANK YOU VERY MUCH
FOR BEING WITH US, A GREAT
JOB.
>> SO MANY PEOPLE ARE
WONDERING WHAT IS HAPPENING TO
THE CULTURE OF AMERICA, DOES
THIS SAY SOMETHING ABOUT OUR
CULTURE?
HAVE WE GOTTEN TOO FAR AWAY
FROM PRAYER?
THAT'S FATHER JONATHAN MORRIS'
SUGGESTION, LET'S TALK TO HIM
NEXT.
Um...
Uh...
Hm...
Umm...
Uh...
Oh !
The Windows Phone 8X
by HTC on Verizon.
It features easy
to navigate live tiles
that are simple
to customize.
Just pin what matters most
right to your homescreen.
Exclusively with Data Sense--
a feature that makes the most
of you plan.
Only on Verizon.
PREGO?!
BUT I'VE BOUGHT RAGU FOR YEARS.
[ Thinking ] WONDER WHAT OTHER
QUESTIONABLE CHOICES I'VE MADE?
I CHOOSE DATE NUMBER 2!
WHOOO!
[ sigh of relief ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHOOSE TASTE. CHOOSE PREGO.
>>  CONVERSATIONS SURROUNDING
THIS HORRIBLE SCHOOL TRAGEDY
WILL AT SOME POINTS TURN TO
SECURITY AND PSYCHOLOGY AND OF
COURSE GUNS AND TODAY WE ARE
TALKING ABOUT GOD AND WE'RE
TURNING TO OUR RELIGIOUS
CORRESPONDENT, JONATHAN
MORRIS, WROTE A BOOK DEALING
WITH TRAGEDY.
YOU'VE BEEN THROUGH IT MANY
TIMES BEFORE.
>> ISN'T IT AMAZE TO GO SEE
HOW PEOPLE NATURALLY TURN TO
PRAYER AND GOD IN TOUGH, TOUGH
TIMES AND THAT'S
UNDERSTANDABLE BECAUSE I
BELIEVE THAT AT THE VERY CORE
OF WHO WE ARE.
IT'S WONDERFUL, ALSO, TO SEE
THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES FEELING VERY
COMFORTABLE QUOTING SCRIPTURE
IN A TRAGIC TIME LIKE THIS,
THAT'S GOOD, THAT'S NORMAL,
THAT'S WONDERFUL.
I THINK WE SHOULD ALL FEEL
JUST PASS COMFORTABLE TO BE
EXPRESSING OUR BELIEF IN GOD,
OUR BELIEVE IN RELIGION EVEN
IN THE GOOD TIME.
>> IT'S THE GUY THAT NEEDS GOD
AND CAN'T BLAME THE PERSON,
PERFECT TOWN, IDYLLIC SCHOOL
AND TEACHERS AND THE GUY THAT
NEEDS YOU IS SHOT IN THE HEAD
NO DOUBT.
>> THAT'S AN INVITATION FOR
ALL OF US TO BE GOING AFTER
AND HELPING PEOPLE WHO ARE
OBVIOUSLY OFF OR OBVIOUSLY--
WE'RE GOING TO HEAR THAT THIS
WAS A SENSELESS ACT.
YES, IT WAS IN A CERTAIN
SENSE, BUT ALSO WE KNOW FROM
YUS LOOKING AT THE
CIRCUMSTANCES, A THE THESE
CASES, IT'S SENSELESS, BUT
THERE'S A CERTAIN FORMULA
HERE.
THERE'S ALMOST ALWAYS MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES.
THERE'S ALSO PERSONAL
RESPONSIBILITY IN MOST OF
THESE KAY CASES, SOMEBODY
DECIDES TO TAKE THEIR ANGER
OUT ON SOMEBODY ELSE.
THERE'S A THIRD ELEMENT, WE'VE
BEEN HEARING ABOUT, THERE'S
EVIL.
EVIL IS SPIRITUAL FORCE AND
AFFECTS US AT THE CORE OF WHO
WE ARE.
THAT'S WHY WOULD HE HE NEED
PASTORS, MOTHERS, FATHERS,
COMMUNITIES, TO MAKE SURE
WE'RE NOT MARGINALIZING PEOPLE
WHO ARE ALREADY MARGINALIZING
THEMSELVES AND WE NEED TO FIND
THEM BEFORE THAT HAPPENS.
>> Alisyn: ISN'T THAT
CONTRADICTORY, IF WE SAY THE
PEOPLE ARE MENTALLY ILL AND
OPEN OUR HEARTS AND PUT OUR
ARMS AROUND THEM, BUT THEY'RE
EVIL.
THAT MAKES US LESS
COMPASSIONATE IF THEY'RE EVIL.
>> AND WE AS HUMAN BEINGS
PSYCHO SO MATTIC, WE'RE BOTH
EMOTIONAL, SPIRITUAL AND
PHYSICAL.
YES, SOMEBODY CAN BE MENTALLY
ILL, BUT ALSO BECAUSE NR'
SPIRITUAL BE INDECLINED TO
EVIL, RIGHT AND TO ACT OUT
ABOUT IT AND THAT'S WHY ALL OF
THESE THINGS, BUILDING
SPIRITUALITY, LOVING, BEING
INVOLVED WITH OUR KIDS IN THIS
WAY.
LET ME GIVE YOU AN EXAMPLE,
SOMETIMES WE TALK ABOUT
FACEBOOK AND TWITTER AND
SOCIAL MEDIA CAN ISOLATE
OURSELVES, WHEN I PUT THOSE
COMMENTS ON MY FACEBOOK AND
TWITTER TODAY, HUNDREDS OF
PEOPLE STARTED WRITING IN AND
OFFERING PRAYERS, WHAT WE CAN
DO IS BE VERY CLOSE TO OUR
KIDS.
HUG THEM, LOVE THEM AND ALSO
BE UNAFRAID TO PRAY WITH THEM.
>> FATHER JONATHAN MORRIS.
>> AND IF YOU CAN'T TALK TO
THEM.
SOMETIMES YOU HAVE TO TWEET
>> Alisyn: THANK YOU, FATHER
JOHN.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
YOU WON'T TAKE MY LIFE.
YOU WON'T TAKE OUR FUTURE.
AIDS AFFECTS US ALL.
EVEN BABIES.
CHEVRON IS WORKING TO STOP
MOTHER-TO-CHILD TRANSMISSION.
OUR EMPLOYEES AND THEIR FAMILIES
ARE PART OF THE FIGHT.
AND WE'RE WINNING.
AT CHEVRON NIGERIA, WE HAVEN'T
HAD A REPORTED CASE IN 12EARS.
AIDS IS STRONG.
BUT WE ARE STRONGER.
AND AIDS...
♪
AIDS IS GOING TO LOSE.
Is bigger than we think ...
Sometimelike the flu.fer fromE.
With aches, fever and chills-
the flu's a really big deal.
So why treat it like
it's a little cold?
There's something
that works differently
than over-the-counter
remedies.
Prescription TAMIFLU attacks
the flu virus at its source.
So don't wait. Call your
doctor right away.
TAMIFLU is prescription
medicine for treating the flu
in adults and children
one year and older
whose flu symptoms started
within the last two days.
Before taking TAMIFLU tell your
doctor if you're pregnant,
nursing. have serious
health conditions,
or take other medicines.
If you develop an allergic
reaction, a severe rash,
or signs of unusual behavior,
stop taking TAMIFLU and call
your doctor immediately.
Children and adolescents in
particular may be at an
increased risk
of seizures, confusion
or abnormal behavior.
The most common
side effects are
mild to moderate nausea
and vomiting.
The flu comes on fast,
so ask your
doctor about TAMIFLU.
Prescription for flu.