ON HIS SHOES HE WILL BE BURIED
WITH A JERSEY NUMBER 80.
NOW MEANS SO MUCH.
ONE OF THE GOOD NEWS STORIES IN
SPORTS.
WHAT A GOOD INSPIRATION FOR THE
KIDS.
>> REMEMBER I TOLD YOU GOVERNOR
NIKKI HALEY SOUTH CAROLINA SHE
GOT TO APPOINT SOMEBODY TO
SENATOR DEMINT'S SPEECH SHE HAS
CHOSEN BILL SCOTT WHO IS A
FRESHMAN.
HE WILL BE SOUTH CAROLINA'S
FIRST BLACK SENATOR AND THE ONLY
AFRICAN AMERICAN SENATOR IN THE
UNITED STATES SENATE AT THIS
TIME.
ALL OF THE VICTIM'S FAMILIES
HEARTFELT FEELINGS FROM US
TONIGHT.
THAT'S IT FOR THE 5.
THANK YOU.
SEE YOU HERE TOMORROW.
>> THIS IS A FOX NEWS ALERT.
THE LONGEST SERVING SENATOR IN
U.S. HISTORY HAS DIED.
UNITED STATES DEMOCRATIC SENATOR
DANIEL INOUYE WORLD WAR II
VETERAN MEDAL OF HONOR RECIPIENT
DIED FROM RESPIRATORY
COMPLICATIONS AT 5:00 THIS
AFTERNOON.
TODAY AT WALTER REED NATIONAL
MILITARY MEDICAL CENTER.
SENATE MAJORITY LEADER CALLED
INOUYE ONE OF THE GRATES OF THE
CHAMBER.
MITCH MCCONNELL SAID HE HAD
EVERY REASON TO BRING ATTENTION
TO HIMSELF BUT QUOTE NEVER DID.
WE WILL HAVE MORE ON THE LIFE OF
THE SENATOR LATER IN THE SHOW.
THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
MASSACRE THAT LEFT 20 CHILDREN
AND 6 ADULTS DEAD BEGAN BURYING
THE LITTLEST VICTIMS AS FUNERALS
WERE HELD FOR TWO 6-YEAR-OLD
BOYS INCLUDING ONE WHOSE TWIN
SISTER SURVIVED THAT RAMPAGE.
CONNECTICUT STIT POLICE
LIEUTENANT SADIE TAILS WERE
QUOTE TOO DIFFICULT TO DISCUSS
FKTD THEY COULD HOLD THE SCHOOL
AND THE HOME OF ADAM LANZA
ACCOUNTABLE.
THEY PLEDGE TO SEEK CHANGE AS HE
SLOWLY RECITED THE FIRS NAMES OF
THE VICTIMS.
TODAY WHITE HOUSE PRESS
SECRETARY JAY CARNEY WARNED THAT
NO SINGLE ACTION OR PIECE OF
LEGISLATION WILL PREVENT
SHOOTINGS LIKE FRIDAY'S ATTACK.
>> CROWDS LINED UP FOR THE FIRST
OF 26 FUNERALS STARTING WITH
6-YEAR-OLD NOAH POZNER.
THEY FELL FWHOOK THE RITUAL OF
NEVER KNOWING AGAIN.
>> THEY WON'T BE ABLE TO DRIVE
GO ON THE FIRST DATE.
>> IT DOESN'T JUST BREAK OUR
HEARTS, IT SHATTERS THEM.
>> NEITHER SENATE LEADER CALLED
FOR ANY NEW GUN LAWS.
>> IT WAS TIED TO THE CRUSADE
THEY KNEW ABOUT.
>> TAKING POSITIONS ON COMMON
SENSE MEASURE THAT IS HE
BELIEVES SHOULD BE TAKEN TO HELP
ADDRESS THIS PROBLEM.
HE MADE CLEAR THAT MORE NEEDS TO
BE DONE.
>> FAR MORE HESITANT THAN THE
PRESIDENT AT THAT DRAMATIC
PRAYER SERVICE.
>> I WILL USE WHATEVER POWER
THIS OFFICE HOLDS TO ENGAGE MY
FELLOW CITIZENS FROM LAW
ENFORCEMENT AND MENTAL HEALTH
PROFESSIONALS TO PARENTS AND
EDUCATORS IN AN EFFORT AIMED AT
PREVENTING MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE
THIS.
BECAUSE WHAT CHOICE DO WE HAVE?
>> TODAY NEW YORK CITY MAYOR
MICHAEL BLOOMBERG MOCKED THE
IDEA OF THE FISCAL CLIFF MIGHT
DISTRACT THE ABILITY TO COME
TOGETHER ON GUN CONTROL.
>> IF CONGRESS AND THE PRESIDENT
CAN'T FOCUS ON TWO THINGS AT
ONCE WHO ON EARTH DID WE ELECT?
>> IN EARLY 2011 THE PRESIDENT
MADE SIMILAR PROMISES IN TUCSON
NOTING IT WAS FINALLY TIME TO
STOP GUN VIOLENCE WHILE ADDING
QUOTE LIKE THE MA JOER OF THE OF
AMERICANS I BELIEVE THE SECOND
AMENDMENT GIVES THE RIGHT TO
BEAR ARMS.
MY ADMINISTRATION HAS NOT
CURTAILED THE RIGHTS OF GUN
OWNERS IT HAS EXPANDED THEM.
CARNEY WAS PRESSED TO NAME ONE
ACTION THE PRESIDENT HAS TAKEN
SINCE THEN.
>> WE TAKEN STEPS ON THE ISSUE
OF BACKGROUND CHECKS TO MAKE THE
SYSTEM MORE THOROUGH AND
COMPLETE.
>> WHAT MIGHT BE DIFFERENT IN
THIS TRAGEDY IS ALL OF THE
CHILDREN INVOLVED MAKING IT
DIFFICULT FOR THE NATIONAL RIFLE
ASSOCIATION TO STOP ACTION.
>> TODAY CENTRIST DEMOCRATS WITH
A RATINGS BY THE NRA SAID FOR
THE FIRST TIME THEY ARE OPEN TO
NEW GUN LAWS.
WARNER TWEETED THIS WAS A GAME
CHANGER.
MANSON SEEMED TO AGREE.
>> THE ONE AREA OF POSSIBLE
AGREEMENT IS DIANE FINE STEIN IS
REINTRODUCING A BAN ON ASSAULT
WEAPONS.
THAT'S SOMETHING THE PRESIDENT
DOES SUPPORT.
THE PRESIDENT AND VICE PRESIDENT
MET WITH CABINET SECRETARIES TO
START DISCUSSING WHAT REGULATION
THEY MAY COME UP WITH.
>> ED, THANK YOU IN THE NORTH
LAWN.
>> VIOLENCE IS FORCING EDUCATORS
TO CONFRONT WHAT CAN DTHEY DO I
IF ANYTHING TO MAKE SCHOOLS
SAFER AND MORE SECURE.
>> AT THIS TIME WE ARE GOING TO
HAVE A MOMENT OF SILENCE.
>> AT DISTRICT HEIGHTS
ELEMENTARY IN MARYLAND SOUTHEAST
OF THE CAPITOL FIRST GRADERS
RECEIVED NEW LESSONS IN LIFE AND
THE LOSS OF IT.
>> PART OF THE MOMENT OF SILENCE
YOU THINK ABOUT HOW WE CAN
CONTINUE TO CARE FOR EACH OTHER.
>> ACROSS AMERICA LOCAL POLICE
TOUCHED BASE WITH SCHOOL
SECURITY OFFICERS PROCEDURES FOR
SAFETY DRILLS WERE DUSTED OFF
AND REVISITED.
>> WE ARE SITTING DOWN AT THE
TABLE NOW TO COME UP WITH
DIFFERENT WAYS TO KEEP INTRUDERS
AND SUSPICIOUS PERSONS OUT OF
OUR SCHOOLS.
>> THE MESSAGE HAMMERED HOME TO
PARENTS WE ARE TRAINED FOR
SITUATIONS LIKE THIS.
>> I THINK THERE HAVE BEEN
SEVERAL INSTANCES SINCE
COLUMBINE THAT WERE STOPPED
RESULT OF HEIGHTENED AWARENESS
OF SCHOOL VIOLENCE.
>> COUNSELORS AND PSYCHOLOGISTS
BRACED FOR TOUGH QUESTIONS THE
CHILDR UNIQUELY COME POSE.
>> IT IS IMPORTANT WE HAVE AGE
APPROPRIATE DISCUSSIONS AS THE
STUDENTS BRING THEIR CONCERNS
FORWARD.
>> ESPECIALLY WITH YOUNG
CHILDREN.
IT MAY NOT BE WITH WORDS THAT
THEY ASK THEIR QUESTIONS.
IT MAY BE WITH THEIR BEHAVIOR.
>> PRINCIPALS DECIDED TO WAIT
UNTIL THEY RAISED IT ON THEIR
OWN.
A PRINCIPAL E-MAILED PARENTS OUR
APPROACH WILL BE TO ADDRESS IT
AS IT COMES UP.
I DON'T WANT ADULT INITIATED
CONVERSATIONS TO IMPRESS MORE ON
THE CHILDREN THAN PARENTS
DESIRE.
STILL ANOTHER PRINCIPAL URGED
PARENTS TO LIMIT THE AMOUNT OF
VIOLENT IMAGERY THEIR KIDS TAKE
IN.
WHILE MEDICAL PROFESSIONALS
ADVOCATED MORE EARLIER ATTENTION
TO CHILDREN PSYCHOLOGICAL
WELL-BEING.
>> IF WE DEALT MORE
PREVENTATIVELY MORE OUTPATIENT
THERAPY FOR MENTAL HEALTH PEOPLE
MORE INPATIENT IN CRISIS SO THEY
DON'T GET TURNED OUT ON THE
STREET YOU WOULD LESSEN THE
CHANCES OF SOME KIND OF VIOLENCE
SNAPPING OR SOME KIND OF VIOLENT
INCIDENT.
>> SCHOOLS IN RICH FIELD
CONNECTICUT 20 MILES SOUTHWEST
OF NEWTOWN WENT ON LOCK DOWN
AFTER REPORTS OF A MAN WITH A
RIFLE TURNED OUT TO BE AN
UMBRELLA.
THE MAN WAS CHARGED WITH BREECH
OF POLICE AND POLICE IN LOS
ANGELES ARRESTED A MAN FOR
POSTING THREATS ON FACEBOOK FOR
AREA SCHOOL CHILDREN AT THE
APARTMENT WHERE HIS PARENTS
LIVED.
THEY REPORTED FINDING 6 HAND
GUNS TWO RIFLES AND A SHOT GUN.
BRETT?
>> THANK YOU.
STOCKS STARTED THE WEEK UP.
THE DOW ADDED 100.
THE S&P 500 GAINED 17.
THE NASDAQ CLOSED 39 AHEAD.
AS WE TOLD YOU AT THE TOP OF THE
SHOW U.S. SENATOR DANIEL INOUYE
MEDAL OF HONOR RECIPIENT AND
SENIOR SENATOR DIED FROM
RESPIRATORY COMPLICATIONS AT
WALTER REED NATIONAL MILITARY
MEDICAL CENTER.
HAWAII HAS NEVER BEEN A STATE
WITHOUT INOUYE IN THE BODY.
HE FIRST SERVED IN THE HOUSE
WHEN HAWAII JOINED THE UNION IN
1959 MOVED TO THE SENATE IN
1962.
BY THE END OF HIS CAREER HE WAS
THE MOST SENIOR MEMBER OR
PRESIDENT PRO-TEM OF THE SENATE
MAKING HIM THIRD IN LINE FOR THE
PRESIDENCY.
EVIDENCES PRESIDENT PRO-TEM AND
HE WAS SENIOR MEMBER OF THE
MAJORITY PARTY.
HE WAS BEHIND VICE PRESIDENT
BIDEN AND SPEAKER BOEHNER.
PATRICK LEHEY NEXT IN LINE.
HE JOINED THE SENATE IN 1974.
IN -- INOUYE THIS IS WHAT HE
SAID MARKING THE PEARL HAR DOBO
ATTACK DECEMBER 7, 2011.
>> THE BOMBING OF PEARL HARBOR 7
YEARS AGO BEGAN A PERIOD OF MY
LIFE WHEN I BECAME I HOPE A GOOD
AMERICAN.
IT IS SOMETHING THAT I WILL
NEVER FORGET.
IT CHANGED MY LIFE FOREVER.
SOMETHING OF INTEREST AT THIS
MOMENT.
I HOPE THAT WE WILL REMEMBER
DECEMBER THE 7TH.
I HOPE WE WILL REMEMBER 9-11.
THAT WAS JUST A FEW YEARS AGO BE
PEOPLE ARE BEGINNING TO FORGET
9-11.
IF DECEMBER THE 7TH IS GOING TO
TEACH US ANYTHING, IT SHOULD BE
THAT WE MUST REMAIN VIGILANT AT
ALL TIMES.
KNOTTED JUST TO AVOID WAR BUT
VIGILANT AMONG OURSELVES THAT WE
WOULD NOT USE THIS AS A
JUSTIFICATION TO SET ASIDE OUR
MOST HONORED DOCUMENT, THE
CONSTITUTION.
I HOPE IT WILL NEVER HAPPEN
AGAIN.
>> ACCORDING TO HIS STAFF, A
STATEMENT THEY PUT OUT TONIGHT
HIS LAST WORDS WERE ALOHA,
HAWAII DEMOCRATIC SENATOR DANIEL
INOUYE DIED TONIGHT AT 88.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS DECEMBER, REMEMBER --
YOU CAN STAY IN
AND LIKE SOMETHING...
OR YOU CAN GET OUT THERE
AND ACTUALLY LIKE SOMETHING.
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
FIVE DAYS LATER,
I HAD A MASSIVE HEART ATTACK.
BAYER ASPIRIN WAS THE FIRST
THING THE EMTS GAVE ME.
NOW, I'M ON
A BAYER ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Male Announcer ] BE SURE
TO TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE YOU BEGIN
AN ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Woman ]
LEARN FROM MY STORY.
>> WITH FEARS OF A FISCAL CLIFF
LOOMING ANOTHER FACE TO FACE
MEETING WITH THE WHITE HOUSE
BETWEEN BOTH SIDES SPARKS HOPE
THAT A DEAL MIGHT BE IN THE
WORKS.
AS MIKE EMMANUEL REPORTS A LOT
OF WORK STILL NAEDZ TO BE DONE.
>> A MEETING BETWEEN OBAMA AND
SPEAKER BOEHNER LASTED 45
MINUTES LATE THIS MORNING TRYING
TO WORK OUT A DEAL ON THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
HE DID NOT WORK WITH REPORTERS
AFTER THE FACE TO FACE SESSION
WITH OBAMA.
THE KEY MOMENTS CAME IN A PHONE
CALL FRIDAY WHEN THEY HAD TAX
RATES FOR THOSE MAKING
$1 MILLION.
THE WHITE HOUSE IS PUSHING TAX
RATES FOR THOSE MAKING MORE THAN
250,000 DOLLARS.
THE COMPONENTS OF A DEAL
ACCORDING TO SOURCES CLOSE TO
BOEHNER IS 1 TRILLION ON A CUT
ONE IN REVENUE.
THE LEGISLATIVE PROCESS THROUGH
NEXT YEAR CAN YOU INCLUDED
PAYROLL TAX CUTS AND TAX
EXTENDERS.
INCREASING IT WITH PRESIDENT
OBAMA WANTED IT AS PART OF A
FISCAL CLIFF DEAL.
IT WOULD REQUIRE CUTS AND
REFORMS OF A GREATER AMOUNT BUT
THE WHITE HOUSE SPOKESMAN DIDN'T
GET INTO TOO MANY SPECIFICS BUT
MADE A PITCH FOR MORE TAX
REVENUE.
>> THE PRESIDENT BELIEVES IN THE
PARAMETERS OF POTENTIAL
AGREEMENT WITH CLEAR.
IT IS ALSO THE CASE THAT WE HAVE
NOT SEEN A PROPOSAL BESIDES THE
PRESIDENTS THAT ACHIEVED THE
BALANCE THE PRESIDENT EXISTS BE
PART OF THE DEAL.
>> HERITAGE ACTION ARE HAMMERING
HOUSE REPUBLICANS FOR
NEGOTIATING WITH THEMSELVES IN
PUBLIC ABOUT HOW HIGH TO
INCREASE TAXES.
>> MIKE EMANUEL ON THE HILL.
WHAT ABOUT THIS SENDIPENDING IS
WE KEEP HEARING SO MUCH ABOUT.
WHERE ARE YOUR TAX DOLLARS
GOING.
WE TAKE A LOOK IN PART ONE OF
THE SERIES "THE COST OF
SPENDING."
>> WE CAN'T SPEND OURSELVES
RICH.
>> PRESIDENTS HAVE BEEN TALKING
ABOUT THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT
SPENDING APPETITE FOR DECADES.
PRESIDENT REAGAN.
>> WHAT AILS USABLE BE S -- US
BE SIMPLY PUT THE PRESIDENT IS
GROWING TOO BIG.
>> THIS GOVERNMENT IS TOO BIG
AND SPENDS TOO MUCH.
>> PRESIDENT CLINTON.
>> THIS IS THE LARGEST DEFICIT
REDUCTION PLAN IN HISTORY.
>> PRESIDENT GEORGE W. BUSH.
>> AMERICAN FAMILIES HAVE TO
BALANCE THEIR BUDGETS SO SHOULD
THEIR GOVERNMENT.
>> EVERY DAY FAMILIES SACRIFICE
TO LIVE WITHIN THEIR MEANS.
THEY DESERVE A GOVERNMENT THAT
DOES THE SAME.
>> IN THE RECENT TALKS TO AVOID
THE SO-CALLED FISCAL CLIFF JOHN
BOEHNER INSISTS THE PRESIDENT
HAS BEEN SINGING A DIFFERENT
TUNE.
>> IT IS CLEAR THE PRESIDENT IS
NOT SERIOUS CUTTING SPENDING.
BUT SPEND SOMETHING THE PROBLEM.
>> YOU HEAR THE TALKING HEADS
EVERY DAY THE BACK AND FORTH
EVERY DAY.
BUT HAVE YOU TRIED RECENTLY TO
GET YOUR HEAD AROUND HOW MUCH
THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT DOLES OUT
EVERY DAY?
>> WHEN IT COMES TO GOVERNMENT
SPENDING WHAT'S THE VERY BASIC
MATH OF THE PROBLEM WE HAVE
GOTTEN OURSELVES INTO?
EACH DAY DUG THE MONTH OF
NOVEMBER THE GOVERNMENT BROUGHT
IN A LITTLE MORE THAN $5 BILLION
OF REVENUE.
THAT'S A LOT OF MONEY.
WE SPEND MORE THAN 11 BILLION A
DAY.
THE DIFFERENCE AS YOU CAN
CLEARLY SEES ROUGHLY $6 BILLION.
HOW CAN WE KEEP SPENDING MORE
THAN WE TAKE IN?
ECONOMISTS WE TALK TO SAID IT'S
SIMPLE, WE CAN'T.
THE GOVERNMENT AM SPENDS MORE
THAN $11 BILLION A DAY.
WHERE DOES THE MAJORITY OF THAT
MONEY GO?
HERE ARE THE TOP FOUR OUT LAYS
AT THE TOP OF THE LIST
DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN
SERVICES WHICH GOES THROUGH 3
BILLION OF TAX DOLLARS A DAY.
SOCIAL SECURITY IS A CLOSE
SECOND AT 2 AND A HALF BILLION
DOLLARS DAILY.
MILITARY PROGRAMS COME IN AT
1.8 BILLION DAILY.
ECONOMISTS SAY NUMBER 4 DOWN
THERE AT THE BOTTOM THE SMALLEST
DAILY OUT LAY OF THE GROUP
DROPPING DOWN TO 854 MILLION A
DAY WE DON'T GET ANYTHING FOR
THAT.
THAT'S $854 MILLION OF INTEREST
THAT OUR COUNTRY PAYS ON OUR
DEBT EVERY SINGLE DAY.
>> FORMER DEMOCRATIC SENATOR
EVAN BOW.
>> WE CAN'T KEEP BORROWING LIKE
THIS OR WE WILL HAVE THE SAME
PROBLEMS THAT EUROPE IS HAVING.
THAT IS ONE OF THE FRUSTRATING
THINGS.
THEY ARE NOT THEORETICAL.
THAT'S NOT A CLASSROOM EXERCISE.
YOU CAN LOOK AT EUROPE AND SEE
WHAT HAPPENS IF WE CONTINUE DOWN
THIS PATH VERY MUCH LONGER.
>> ALEX RID MAN BILL CLINTON'S
BUDGET DIRECTOR PUT THE BULK OF
THE SPENDING PROBLEMS ON THE
PROMISES TO MEDICARE MEDICAID
AND LESSER EXTENT SOCIAL
SECURITY.
>> THEY WILL DRIVE FEDERAL
SPENDING OCCUPY FASTER NAN OUR
ECONOMY CAN GROW.
REVENUES WON'T KEEP UP.
WE HAVE A PROBLEM.
IF YOU DON'T HAVE ENOUGH
REVENUES TO PAY FOR THE SPENDING
YOU HAVE TO BORROW.
ON THE TRACK THAT WE ARE ON IF
WE GO ON DOING WHAT IS IN THE
LAW OVER THE NEXT SEVERAL
DECADES, OUR PUBLIC DEBT WILL
RISE FAST YOU ARE THAN OUR
ECONOMY WILL GROW.
WHEN THAT HAPPENS YOU HAVE REAL
PROBLEM.
YOU HAVE TO PAY INTEREST ON THAT
DEBT AND CREDITORS SEE THAT YOUR
DEBT IS RISING FASTER THAN YOUR
ECONOMY IS GROWING SO THEY
CHARGE MORE AND MORE.
IT IS A VERY BAD SITUATION.
>> ARTHUR BROOKS WITH THE
AMERICAN ENTERPRISE INSTITUTE
FINDS SUR RENT DEBATES ABOUT
HIGHER TAXES MISGUIDED WITH
FEDERAL SPENDING ON OVER DRIVE.
>> IT IS AS SIMPLE AS A FAMILY
THAT DOES THAT.
THE PROBLEM IS RIGHT NOW YOU
HAVE A SITUATION IN WHICH THE
GOVERNMENT IN IT'S OVER SPENDING
WAYS TRIES TO RATIONALIZE IT BY
SAYING THAT ACTUALLY THE PROBLEM
IS WE ARE UNDER TAXING THE
AMERICAN PUBLIC.
LIKE YOUR RESPONSIBLE BROTHER IN
LAW RUNS UP HIS CREDIT CARD GOES
BUST THE REAL PROBLEM IS BECAUSE
YOU STOPPED SENDING ME CHECKS.
IT'S CRAZY.
THAT'S YOIRRESPONSIBLE.
WE HAVE A DEBTOR NATION THAT HAS
THE MENTALITY IF ONLY WE COULD
SQUEEZE MORE MONEY OUT OF PEOPLE
WHO ARE WORKING HONESTLY EARNING
THEIR LIVING WE CAN SOLVE THIS
PROBLEM FBLT THE TRUTH OF THE
MATTER IS OUR COUNTRY SPENDS TOO
MUCH.
>> TAKE A CLOSER LOOK AT THE
DEFICIT TOMORROW IN PART 2.
SO WHAT DO YOU WANT THE
GOVERNMENT TO SPEND YOUR MONEY
ON?
LET ME KNOW ON TWITTER.
YOU CAN FOLLOW ME AT BRET BAIER.
STILL AHEAD SUCCESS IS A BAD
THING IN ONE TRY.
WE WILL EXPLAIN.
PLUS CONGRESSMAN KIM SCOTT IS
HEADED TO THE U.S. SENATE.
SEE HOW CONSERVATIVES RATE THE
REPLACEMENT OF TIM DEMINT.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
ROBITUSSIN® LIQUID FORMULA
SOOTHES YOUR THROAT ON CONTACT
AND THE ACTIVE INGREDIENT
RELIEVES YOUR COUGH.
ROBITUSSIN®. DON'T SUFFER
THE COUGHEQUENCES™.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] CAMPBELL'S
GREEN BEAN CASSEROLE.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO
HE LOVES RISK.
BUT WHETHER
HE'S CLIMBING EVEREST,
SCUBA DIVING THE
GREAT BARRIER REEF WITH SHARKS,
OR JUMPING INTO THE MARKET,
HE GOES WITH PEOPLE HE TRUSTS,
WHICH IS WHY HE TRADES
WITH A COMPANY
THAT DOESN'T NICKEL AND DIME
HIM WITH HIDDEN FEES.
SO HE CAN WORRY
ABOUT OTHER THINGS,
LIKE WHAT THE MARKET IS DOING
AND BEING READY,
NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENS,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE,
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
[ Male Announcer ]
JILL AND HER MOUTH HAVE LIVED
A GREAT LIFE.
BUT SHE HAS SOME DENTAL ISSUES
SHE'S NOT HAPPY ABOUT.
SO I INTRODUCED JILL
TO CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SELECTED FOR PEOPLE OVER 50.
PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE IS A
TOOTHPASTE THAT DEFENDS AGAINST
TENDER, INFLAMED GUMS,
SENSITIVITY AND WEAK ENAMEL.
CONDITIONS PEOPLE OVER 50
EXPERIENCE.
CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SO JILL CAN KEEP LIVING
THE GOOD LIFE.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
>> WEAPONS OF MASS DESTRUCTION
COULD FALL INTO THE HANDS OF
ISLAMIC EXTREMISTS WHO COULD USE
THE WEAPONS AGAINST THE SYRIAN
PEOPLE AND BLAME ASSAD'S
GOVERNMENT.
THEY HAVE PLANS IN PLACE FOR
RESPONDING TO POSSIBLE SCENARIOS
INVOLVING CHEMICAL WEAPONS IF
NECESSARY.
THEY HIT A NUMBER OF TARGETS IN
ETHNIC LEE DISPUTED AREAS.
DEADLIEST ATTACKS HAPPENED IN
MOSUL WHERE IT KILLED 7 AND
SOUTH CAROLINA GOVERNOR NIKKI
HALEY HAS CHOSEN THE FIRST BLACK
U.S. SENATOR IN STATE HISTORY TO
REPLACE OUTGOING JIM DEMINT.
WE HAVE DETAILS ABOUT A
CONSERVATIVE.
>> ALL THINGS ARE TRULY POSSIBLE
IN THIS SITUATION.
-- NATION.
>> TIM SCOTT GREW UP IN POVERTY
BUT WITH A SINGLE MOTHER WHO
REFUSE TO DO GIVE UP ON HIM WILL
BE THE FIRST AFRICAN AMERICAN
U.S. SENATOR IN SOUTH CAROLINA
HISTORY.
>> THE FACT THAT YOU HAVE A
BLACK U.S. SENATOR MEANS YOU
HAVE SOMEONE WHO PRESENTS
LITERALLY A DIFFERENT FACE ON
THE PARTY IF YOU WILL AND
PERHAPS CAN RELATE TO CURRENTLY
NONREPUBLICAN VOTERS.
>> SHE ASKED SCOTT TO FILL THE
SEAT OF JIM DEMINT SHE IS AWARE
IT MAKES HISTORY BUT THAT DIDN'T
DRIVE HER DECISION.
>> IT IS VERY IMPORTANT TO ME AS
A MINORITY FEMALE THAT
CONGRESSMAN SCOTT EARNED THIS
SEAT.
HE LEARNED THIS SEAT FOR THE
PERSON THAT HE IS.
HE EARNED THIS SEAT FOR THE
RESULTS HE HAS SHOWN.
>> SOCIAL AND FISCAL
CONSERVATIVES PRAISED THE PICK.
PRO-LIFE SUSAN B. ANTHONY LIST
SAID QUOTE CONGRESSMAN TIM
SCOTT'S RISE TO THE SENATE IS
GREAT NEWS FOR THE COUNTRY AND
PRO-LIFE MOVEMENT.
MARTIN OF THE TEA PARTY PATRIOT
SAID IT IS POSITIVE SET FOR THE
TEA PARTY PATRIOTS FOR
CONSTITUTIONALLY LIMITED
GOVERNMENT AND FREE MARKET.
TODAY SCOTT WHO WILL HAVE TO RUN
AGAIN IN A SPECIAL ELECTION FOR
2014 FOR A CHANCE TO SERVE OUT
DEMINT'S FULL TERM SAYS HE
REMAINS FOCUSED ON FISCAL
DISCIPLINE TO WASHINGTON.
>> WE NEED TO MAKE DIFFICULT
DECISIONS.
OFTEN WE HAVE CONVERSATIONS
ABOUT HOW TO CREATE ENOUGH
REVENUE TO SOLVE THE PROBLEM.
I LEARNED EARLY IN MY 20s IF YOU
HAVE A PROBLEM WITH SPENDING
THERE'S NOT ENOUGH REVENUE TO
MAKE UP FOR IT.
WE HAVE A SPENDING PROBLEM,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN IN AMERICA.
KNOTTED A REVENUE -- NOT A
REVENUE PROBLEM.
>> HE EXPECTS TO BE SWORN IN ON
JANUARY 3RDRD.
ONCE SCOTT GIVE
>> THANK YOU.
A QUICK PROGRAMMING NOTE BOTH
SENATE TIM SCOTT AND NIKKI HALEY
WILL JOIN GRETA VAN SUSTEREN ON
TONIGHT'S ON THE RECORD AT
10:00 P.M. EASTERN.
WHY SECRETARY OF STATE CLINTON
IS NOT TESTIFYING ABOUT BENGHAZI
THIS WEEK.
IT SAYS POLITICS MAKES STRANGE
BED FELLOWS.
CASE IN POINT ENERGY EXPORTS
NEXT.
COPD makes it hard
to breathe,
but with ADVAIR,
I'm breathing better.
So now I can be in
the scene.
ADVAIR is
clinically proven to help
significantly improve
lung function.
Unlike most COPD medications,
ADVAIR contains both an
anti-inflammatory
and a
long-acting bronchodilator
working together to help improve
your lung function all day.
ADVAIR won't
replace fast-acting inhalers
for sudden symptoms
and should not be used more
than twice a day.
People with
COPD taking ADVAIR
may have a higher chance
of pneumonia.
ADVAIR may increase your
risk of osteoporosis
and some eye problems.
Tell your doctor
if you have a heart condition
or high blood pressure before
taking ADVAIR.
If you're still
having difficulty breathing,
ask your doctor if including
ADVAIR could help
improve your lung function.
Get your
first full
prescription
free
and save
on refills
at
ADVAIRcopd.com.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT STARTED LONG AGO.
THE JOY OF GIVING SOMETHING
EVERYTHING YOU'VE GOT.
IT TAKES PASSION.
AND IT'S NOT LETTING UP
ANYTIME SOON.
AT UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company,
WE UNDERSTAND THAT COMMITMENT.
AND ALWAYS HAVE.
SO DOES AARP,
AN ORGANIZATION
SERVING THE NEEDS
OF AMERICANS 50 AND OVER
FOR GENERATIONS.
SO IT'S NO SURPRISE
MILLIONS HAVE CHOSEN
AN AARP Medicare Supplement
Insurance Plan,
INSURED BY UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company.
LIKE ALL STANDARDIZED
MEDICARE SUPPLEMENT PLANS,
THEY HELP COVER
SOME OF THE EXPENSES
MEDICARE DOESN'T PAY.
AND SAVE YOU UP TO THOUSANDS
IN OUT-OF-POCKET COSTS.
TO FIND OUT MORE,
REQUEST YOUR
FREE DECISION GUIDE.
CALL OR GO ONLINE TODAY.
AFTER ALL,
WHEN YOU'RE GOING THE DISTANCE,
IT'S NICE TO HAVE
THE EXPERIENCE AND COMMITMENT
TO GO ALONG WITH YOU.
KEEP DREAMING. KEEP DOING.
GO LONG.
>> SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON INSISTED TODAY SHE
REMAINED OPEN TO TESTIFYING IF
FRONT OF LAWMAKER ABOUTS THE
DEADLY ATTACK ON THE CONSULATE
IN LIBYA.
WHEN IS ANOTHER QUESTION.
KATHERINE HARRIS IS HERE TO
EXPLAIN.
>> THE HOUSE AND SENATE FOREIGN
AFFAIRS COMMITTEE SECRETARY OF
STATE SAID THERE'S A POSSIBILITY
SHE MAY TESTIFY ON THE BENGHAZI
TERRORIST ATTACK IN THE FUTURE
BUT OFFERED NO DATE CERTAIN.
IN THE MEANTIME CLINTON WILL NOT
TESTIFY THIS WEEK AS PLANNED.
SPOKES AMERICPERSON SAID SHE WA
GO TO THE HEARINGS BUT HEALTH
ISSUES INCLUDING STOMACH VIRUS
THAT LED TO DEHYDRATION AND A
BAD FALL GOT IN THE WAY.
THIS IS HOW THE STATE DEPARTMENT
TRIED TO EXPLAIN IT.
>> THE SECRETARY HAD ANTICIPATED
TESTIFYING.
SHE HAD COMMITTED TO DO SO WITH
THE TWO COMMITTEE SHARES.
AS WE PUT OUT ON SATURDAY, SHE
IS STILL UNDER THE WEATHER.
SHE WAS DIAGNOSED AS HAVING
SUFFERED A CONCLUSION AND HER
DOCTORS HAVE URGED HER TO STAY
HOME THIS WEEK.
>> WHILE CLINTON IS AT HOME
RECOVERING HER CONCUSSION HER
AIDS SAY SHE IS REVIEWING THE
FINDINGS OF THE INVESTIGATION
INTO THE BENGHAZI TERRORIST
ATTACKS.
TWO DEPUTIES WILL TESTIFY IN HER
PLACE ALONG WITH FORMER
AMBASSADOR PICKERING AND MIKE
MULLEN WHO LED THE
INVESTIGATION.
ON SUNDAY THE HEAD OF HOUSE
FOREIGN AFFAIRS SAYS CLINTON
MUST TESTIFY.
THAT IS THE PROBLEM WITH THE
ADMINISTRATION THEY WANTED TO
HAVE ALL OF THE HEARINGS AND
BRIEFINGS WITH A SECURE SETTING.
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE WANTED TO
KNOW WHAT THE STATE BEPT ARE
DOING TO KEEP THE DIPLOMATS
SAFE.
>> FIVE DAYS AFTER THE ATTACK
THAT KILLED FOUR AMERICANS AND
U.S. AMBASSADOR THEY TOOK
CLINTON'S PLACE.
RICE SAY SHE WAS ASKED TO SUB
FOR THE SECRETARY.
THE BOTTOM LINE IS CLINTON HAS
BEEN UNAVAILABLE ON TWO
OCCASIONS TO FIT PUBLICLY ON
BEHALF OF THE BENGHAZI TERRORIST
ATTACKS.
>> YOU KNOW THAT ARGUMENT ABOUT
THE FISCAL CLIFF IS RAGING HERE
IN WASHINGTON.
ANOTHER POTENTIAL SHOW DOWN IS
UNDERWAY.
THIS ONE IS ABOUT HOW TO FUND
THE RECOVERY FROM HURRICANE
SANDY.
THE SENATE GANDHI BAIT OVER A
SUPPLEME
-- SENATE DEBATED.
HOUSE REPUBLICANS AND FISCAL
CONSERVATIVES ARE RESISTING
SAYING SANDY RELIEF MONEY NEEDS
TO BE OFFSET WITH CUTS
ELSEWHERE.
>>> AS THE FRACKING REVOLUTION
CONTINUES TO BOOM HERE IN THE
U.S. THE ENERGY DEPARTMENT IS
HARD AT WORK ON A PROPOSAL THEY
SAY WOULD MAXIMIZE PROFITS BY
EXPORTING NATURAL GAS.
A SENIOR CORRESPONDENT JOHN
ROBERTS REPORTS IT IS A
SITUATION SETTING UP UNUSUAL
PARTNERSHIPS.
>> WHEN IS SUCCESS A BAD THING?
JUST ASK THE NATURAL GAS
INDUSTRY.
THE SHALE GAS REVOLUTION
FRACKING AS IT IS CALLED HAS
BEEN SO SUCCESSFUL THE U.S. HAS
BEEN SWAMPED.
>> SHALE GAS TOOK OFF THE
DOMESTIC CRISIS PLUNGED $14 PER
MILL TO AS LOW AS 2.
THE GAS INDUSTRY ASKED THE FEDS
PERMISSION TO BUILD 13 TERMINALS
TO LIQUEFY NATURAL GAS FOR THE
LUCRATIVE EXPORT MARKET.
>> BY EXPORTING WE CREATE MORE
JOBS AND CREATE MORE ECONOMIC
ACTIVITY AND MAKE OURSELVES
ENERGY SECURE.
>> THE BATTLE OVER EXPERTS HAS
CREATED STRANGE BED FELLOWS.
THEY FIND THEMSELVES ARM IN ARM
WITH THE OIL AND GAS INDUSTRIES.
AFTER A REMARK THEY DECLARED
EXPORTS WOULD BE GOOD FOR THE
ECONOMY.
>> WE ARE TALKING ABOUT SELLING
A VALUABLE RESOURCE THAT WE HAVE
IN ABUNDANCE THAT WE CAN PROVIDE
TO OTHER COUNTRIES AT A COST
THAT BRINGS IN VALUABLE MONEY
INTO THE UNITED STATES.
>> DOW CHEMICAL A HUGE CONSUMER
OF NATURAL GAS.
ENVIRONMENTAL GROUPS FEAR
EXPORTS WOULD LEAD TO MORE
FRACKING MORE PRODUCTION OF
GREENHOUSE GASES.
MARQUIS AND DOW ARGUE EXPORTS
COULD BE BAD FOR THE ECONOMY BY
RAISING PRICES AT HOME.
DOW CEO SAYS THE REPORT OFFERS
THE BAFFLING CON CLAUGS TCLUSIOE
BETTER OFFER USING THE NATIONAL
GAS ADVANTAGE TO FUEL GROWTH IN
OTHER REGIONS VERSES
STRENGTHENING THE U.S. ECONOMY.
PRICES WOULDN'T RISE ENOUGH TO
MATTER ADDING DOW'S OPPOSITION
IS FUNDAMENTALLY UNFAIR.
>> WHAT IS GOOD FOR THE GOOSE IS
GOOD FOR THE GANDER.
IF THEY WANT PREMARKET TO WORK
SO WE CAN REDUCE PRODUCT AND
MARKET IT WE SHOULD PRO VIVIDE
SAME STANDARD FROM THE ENERGY
INDUSTRY.
>> SOME ARGUE IT COULD HELP
BRING RUSSIAN DOMINANCE IN THE
MARKET AND PRESSURE IRAN.
BRETT?
>> JOHN, THANK YOU.
>> THE SIGNALS ARE NOW GLARING
THAT PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL
ACTIVELY PURSUE GUN CONTROL IN
COMING WEEKS.
WHERE DOES WASHINGTON STAND AND
WHAT ABOUT THE COMPREHENSIVE
SOLUTION IDEAS AFTER FRIDAY'S
SHOOTING IN CONNECTICUT.
WE WILL LOOK AT ALL OF IT WITH
THE ALL STARS WHEN WE COME BACK.
You see, C-MAX helps
you load your freight,
with its foot-activated
lift gate.
But that's not
all you'll see,
Cause C-MAX also
beats Prius v,
with better MPG.
Say hi to the all-new 47
combined MPG C-MAX Hybrid.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME R CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
to the number 1 club
in the world.
The potential of
Manchester United unlocked.
NYSE Euronext.
Unlocking the world's potential.
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS I WILL
USE WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE
HOLDS TO EDNGAGE MY FELLOW
CITIZENS FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT,
MENTAL HEALTH PROFESSIONALS,
PARENTS AND EDUCATORS IN AN
EFFORT AIMED AT PREVENTING MORE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS.
BECAUSE WHAT CHOICE DO WE HAVE?
>> THE PRESIDENT'S POSITION ON
THE ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN HAS NOT
CHANGED.
HE STILL SUPPORTS THE
REENACTMENT.
THIS IS A COMPLEX PROBLEM AND
THERE ARE OBSTACLES TO TAKING
ACTION.
>> I ASK ALL OF MY FRIENDS I
REMEMBER AND ALWAYS HAVE BEEN WE
NEED TO SIT DOWN AND MOVE THIS
DIALOGUE WITO A SENSIBLE REEGEAE
APPROACH.
IT IS PART OF IT NOT ALL OF IT.
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE ON THE
TABLE AND I THINK IT WILL BE.
>> SENATOR JOE MANCHIN TALKING
ABOUT GUN CONTROL MEASURES
POSSIBLY AND WHAT WOULD BE
MOVING FORWARD IN WASHINGTON
AFTER FRIDAY'S SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT.
WHAT WILL MOVE FORWARD?
WE HAVE OUR PANEL.
LAURA YOUR THOUGHTS ABOUT YOU
HEAR ALL OF THIS TALK YOU HEAR
MANCHIN AND OTHERS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK WILL COME OUT
OF THIS?
>> I THINK THE PRESIDENT WILL
BRING UP THE RENEWAL OF THE
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN AND SOME OF
THEM BEING CLIPPED MULTIPLE
WEAPONS CLIPS AMMUNITION CLIPS.
BEYOND THAT, THERE ARE THINGS HE
CAN DO BY EXECUTIVE POWER AND I
WOULDN'T BE SURPRISED IF HE DOES
EXECUTIVE ORDERS RESTRICTING
IMPORT OF CERTAIN GUNS.
YOU ARE SEEING A SHIFT YOU ARE
SEEING SOMEBODY LIKE JOE MANCHIN
WHO IS 100 PERCENT NRA MEMBER.
PAT LEHEY LIBERAL ON MANY THINGS
BUT VERY PRO GUN IN THE PAST IS
GOING TO HOLD HEARINGS NEXT
MONTH.
>> ANOTHER IMPORTANT FIGURE
SENATOR REED WE HAVEN'T HEARD
FROM YET BUT YOU MENTIONED MARK
WARNER WHO SPOKE OUT THIS
AFTERNOON.
TAKE A LOOK AT THIS.
>> AND I ABSOLUTELY BELIEVE
AMERICANS HAVE A RIGHT TO
REASONABLE GUN OWNERSHIP.
BUT I ALSO KNOW AFTER THIS
ENORMOUS TRAGEDY COMING NOT THAT
LONG AFTER THE TRAGEDY OF THE --
MY DAUGHTERS ASKED ME FRIDAY
NIGHT, DAD YOU ARE IN THE SENATE
WHY CAN'T WE PUT REASONABLE
RESTRICTIONS ON ASSAULT WEAPONS
OR THESE RAPID FIRE AMMUNITION
CLIPS.
I DIDN'T HAVE A GOOD ENOUGH
ANSWER FOR THEM.
I AS A NRA MEMBER BELIEVE ENOUGH
IS ENOUGH.
WE ALL NEED TO COME TO THE TABLE
AND END UP WITH APPROPRIATE
RESTRICTIONS.
T
OO THE BIG QUESTION IS WILL
THERE BE THE VOTES?
FOR 20-YEARS THIS ISSUE DOES
NOTHING BUT LOSE AN ELECTION.
THEY CHANGE THEIR MIND ON THIS
THERE WILL BE A SEAT CHANGE.
YOU ARE SEEING SOMETHING
DIFFERENT THAN WHAT HAPPENED IN
THE WAKE OF AURORA AND INDIANA.
CLOSE TO 50 PERCENT OF PEOPLE
THINK THERE SHOULD BE MORE
RESTRICTIONS ON GUNS.
PAST TRAGEDIES HAVEN'T MADE THAT
CHANGE IN PUBLIC OPINION.
>> CHARLES?
>> I UNDERSTAND THIS REFLECTS A
MOVE TO DO THIS.
IN PRINCIPAL I AM NOT OPPOSED TO
IT.
WE A DECADE WITH AN ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN IN THE MID 90s
LASTED FOR A DECADE.
IF YOU LOOK AT THE STUDIES HAD
NO AAPPRECIATEABLE INFLUENCE ON
GUN VIOLENCE.
THERE ARE THREE ELEMENTS IT'S
THE SHOOTER, IT'S THE WEB AND
THE ENVIRONMENT.
THE MAIN THING YOU WANT TO LOOK
AT IS THE WEAPON.
THERE ARE OTHER WAYS OF LOOKING
AT THIS.
IF YOU LOOK AT THE SHOOTER
HIMSELF THE MENTAL HEALTH ISSUE
THE FACT THAT YOU CANNOT GET A
COMMITMENT ON THESE KINDS OF
PEOPLE I AM THINKING MOSTLY OF
JARED LOUGHNER EVERYBODY KNEW HE
WAS A GRENADE READY TO GO OFF.
EVERYBODY SAID THAT.
YOU COULD ONLY STOP HIM AFTER HE
KILLED.
WE MOVED RAD DE TO MAKE IT
DIFFICULT FOR PEOPLE WHO ARE
DANGEROUS.
THAT HAS TO BE ON THE TABLE AND
THERE'S ALSO HOLLYWOOD WITH THE
DE SENSE TIESZATI-- DE SENSEZAT
VIOLENCE.
THEY MAKE IT UBIQUITOUS.
YOU CAN IMAGE THIS KID AUTISTIC
PLAYING THESE GAMES WHERE YOU
MOW PEOPLE DOWN WITHOUT
CONSEQUENCE.
I CAN UNDERSTAND OBAMA SPEAKING
TO THE NRA.
IS HE GOING TO SPEAK TO THE ACLU
ON COMMITMENT AND SPEAK TO
HOLLYWOOD ON AT LEAST VOLUNTARY
CURTAILMENT OF THE OBSCENE
AMOUNT OF VIOLENCE IN THEIR
PRODUCT?
>> BESIDES THE DEMOCRATS
SPEAKING OUT ABOUT CHANGING
THEIR POSITIONS WE HAVE HEARD
ABOUT GUN ADVOCATES PUBLICLY.
WE HEARD LEWEY ON FOX NEWS
SUNDAY WHO MADE A CASE -- WELL
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> ONCE YOU START DRAWING THE
LINE WHERE DO YOU STOP?
THE FACTS ARE EVERY TIME GUNS
HAVE BEEN ALLOWED, CONCEAL CARRY
HAS BEEN ALLOWED THE CRIME RATE
HAS GONE DOWN.
WASHINGTON, D.C. AROUND US OUGHT
TO BE THE SAFEST PLACE IN
AMERICA AND IT'S NOT.
CHICAGO OUGHT TO BE SAFE IT'S
NOT.
THEIR GUN LAWS DON'T WORK.
>> SO THIS DEBATE, I MEAN WE ARE
GOING TO SEE A BIG DEBATE.
>> YOU WILL SEE A IN FAVOR OF
LESS MASS KILLINGS.
YOU HAVE SEEN THE DEVELOPMENT OF
THIS SIMPLE NARRATIVE IN
WASHINGTON WHERE IT IS THE NRA
AND BIG LOBBIES AND BLOCK ANY
PROGRESS OR ANY DISCUSSION OR
A
THESE ISSUES.
IT IS MORE COMPLICATED THAN
THAT.
WHAT MATTERS HERE THE DETAILS
REALLY DO MATTER.
WHAT KINDS OF WEAPONS ARE YOU
CONSIDERING BANNING?
WHAT LEADS TO AN ATROCITY LIKE
THIS ONE?
PART OF THE REASON WE HAVEN'T
HAD THE KIND OF CONSENSUS WE
HAVE BEEN SEEKING IS WE DON'T
AGREE ON WHAT THOSE STEPS SHOULD
BE.
MACHINE GUNS HAVE BEEN ILLEGAL
SINCE 1934.
IT HAS BEEN ILLEGAL TO SELL OR
MANUFACTURER AUTOMATIC WEAPONS.
NO ONE CAN TELL YOU OR GIVE YOU
A STRAIGHT DEFINITION OF WHAT
SEMIAUTOMATIC ACTUALLY MEANS.
>> LET ME READ WHAT SENATOR FINE
STEIN'S BILL SAYS.
STOP THE SALE TRANSFER
MANUFACTURING MORE THAN 100
SPECIFICALLY AIMED FIREARMS AS
WELL AS CERTAIN SEMIAUTOMATIC
RIFLES HAND GUNS DETACHABLE
MAGAZINE
>> THAT IS FROM FISENATOR FINE
STYNES OFFICE.
>> 900 SPECIFIC EXAMPLES OF
WEAPONS.
THERE WAS SOME AGREEMENT ON
POTENTIALLY LIMITING THE SIZE OF
MAGAZINES.
THAT IS THE ONE AREA WHERE YOU
HEAR GUN ADVOCATES AND GUN
CONTROL FOLKS WITH SOME
AGREEMENT OR AT LEAST THE
BEGINNINGS OF SOME AGREEMENT.
>> BUT I MEAN THIS BILL AS YOU
ARE LOOKING AT IT, THIS BILL
COULD IT PASS?
>> I THINK IT COULD PASS BY SOME
VERSION OF IT.
JOE MANCHIN SAID THIS MORNING HE
JUST CAME BACK FROM DEER
HUNTING.
HE NEVER PUTS MORE THAN 3 CLIPS
IN HIS RIFLE.
WHY DO YOU NEED THE MASSIVE
AMOUNTS OF AMMUNITION.
THERE'S ONLY ONE REASON TO MOW
PEOPLE DOWN.
>> THE QUESTION IS WILL IT DO
ANYTHING?
THE BILL LOOKS ALMOST LIKE THE
ONE THAT PASSED IN 1994 WHICH
WAS IN PLACE FOR 10 YEARS AND
HAD NO EFFECT.
PART OF THE REASON WAS IT
ALLOWED AS THIS DOES PEOPLE TO
KEEP THE PWEAPONS THEY ALREADY
HAVE.
IC THERE ARE 24 MILLION OF THESE
MAGAZINES.
IT WOULD TAKE 100 YEARS SUPPLIES
WOULD BE EXHAUSTED.
AUSTRALIA ACCOMPLISHED IT.
THEY HAD BANS ON ANYTHING YOU
COULDN'T HAVE WHAT YOU ALREADY
HAD.
YOU HAD TO SELL IT THE
GOVERNMENT COULD BUY IT.
IF YOU HAD ONE AFTER THAT YOU
WERE RAISED AND IT WORKED.
DO YOU THINK IN THIS COUNTRY WE
WOULD STAND FOR IT.
>> AUSTRALIA ONLY HAD 7 PERCENT
GUN OWNERS.
>> IF SHE HAS THIS EXCEPTION IT
WILL MAKE NO DIFFERENCE IN THE
REAL WORLD BUT EVERYBODY FEELS
GREAT.
>> HOLD ON.
I WAS GOING TO TALK ABOUT THE
FISCAL CLIFF BUT THE SECOND
PANEL WE HAVE MORE TO TALK ABOUT
HERE.
I HAVE AN INTERESTING QUESTION
FROM A VIEWER WHO WROTE IN AND I
THINK WE SHOULD TALK ABOUT IT.
STAY TUNED ON THE OTHER SIDE OF
THIS BREAK.
WERE
>> SOMETIMES WE TAKE VIEWER'S
QUESTIONS AND COMMENTS AND WE
BRING THEM TO YOU.
THIS IS READS:
>> GILLIAN THANKS FOR THE
E-MAIL.
THE AUDIO TO ADDRESS THE MEDIA
COVERAGE OF THIS.
>> IN SOME WAYS IT'S LIKE THE
CLASSIC QUESTION POSEED BY THE
HOLOCAUST FOR EXAMPLE.
THRO
WROTE THE BOOK AFTER THE
HOLOCAUST SAYING THE ONLY
APPROPRIATE ANSWER IS SILENCE.
THERE'S NOTHING YOU CAN SAY IN
WORDS THAT WILL BE ADEQUATE TO
THE TASK IN SOME WAYS DIMINISHES
JUST BY SPEAKING ABOUT IT.
THAT'S ALWAYS THE PROBLEM.
ON THE OTHER HAND SILENCE IS NOT
AN ANSWER THAT SOCIETY CAN
ACCEPT.
IT HAS TO TALK ABOUT IT.
IT HAS TO DISCUSS IT.
AND IN CASES WHERE IT'S NOT ONLY
IN THE PAST BUT IT MAY LIE IN
THE FUTURE THESE KIND OF MASS
KILLINGS YOU HAVE TO TALK ABOUT
IT BECAUSE OF THE POLITICS, WHAT
YOU CAN DO.
SO I DO AGREE WITH THE VIEWER IN
SOME SENSE THAT THERE IS AN OVER
EMPHASIS AND THE BLANKET
COVERAGE IS PERHAPS TOO MUCH.
PEOPLE SAY WHAT DO WE TELL OUR
CHILDREN.
YOU CAN SHUT OFF THE MEDIA SO IT
DOESN'T HAVE TO INVADE THE LIFE
OF A 3-YEAR-OLD, A 6-YEAR-OLD, A
9-YEAR-OLD LIVING IN A DIFFERENT
PART OF THE UNITED STATES BUT IN
THE END IT WILL PENETRATE
BECAUSE THAT'S THE KIND OF
GLOBAL CULTURE WE LIVE IN.
IF IT'S GOING TO LET'S TALK
ABOUT IT AND BE REASONABLE ABOUT
SOLUTIONS THAT MIGHT WORK.
>> NONSTOP COVERAGE.
>> EVERYTHING THE MEDIA DOES IS
TOO MUCH.
ALMOST EVERYTHING THE MEDIA
DOES.
IN ANY EXTREME COVERING ANY KIND
OF HORRIBLE VIOLENT OR EXTREME
SYSTEM.
THERE'S TOO MUCH MEDIA.
>> THERE ARE 24-HOURS A DAY,
THERE'S 24 CHANNELS TEST ON THE
INTERNET.
THERE ARE THINGS PEOPLE CAN
UNDERSTAND AND RELATE TO THEY
CAN'T GET ENOUGH OF IT.
I SYMPATHIZE WITH THE VIEWER.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT WE COULD DO
ABOUT IT.
YOU HAVE TO MOURN APPROPRIATELY
AND FIGURE OUT WHAT TO DO TO
PREVENT SOMETHING LIKE THIS FROM
HAPPENING IN THE FUTURE.
BUT I THINK THAT RESPECT FOR THE
FAMILIES IS THE BOTTOM LINE
HERE.
>> I THINK FOR ME THE QUESTION
IS NOT THAT IT IS BEING COVERED
BUT HOW IT IS BEING COVERED.
I REMEMBER BACK IN JOURNALISM
SCHOOL THIS WAS A LONG TIME AGO
IN ORIGINAL REPORTING IN ONE
CLASS.
ONE OF THE ASSIGNMENTS WAS TO GO
OUT AND FIND IN THE NEWSPAPER
THE FAMILY OF SOMEONE WHO HAD
JUST BEEN KILLED OR JUST DIED
AND SET UP AN INTERVIEW.
I SAID I AM NOT GOING TO DO THAT
PARTICULARLY FOR A JOURNALISM
SCHOOL CLASS.
I HAD A PERSONAL EXPERIENCE
DEALING WITH THIS WHEN THE GULF
WAR WHEN ONE OF MY FRIENDS WAS
KILLED IN THE FIGHTING IN SAUDI
ARABIA.
HIS HOUSE BECAME A CAMP OUT FOR
THESE NEWS CAMERAS AND WE WERE
SO ANGRY AT THE REPORTERS WHO
WERE THERE ALL OF THE TIME.
THE SECOND YOU WALKED OUT OF THE
FRONT DOOR THEY WERE THERE WITH
A MICROPHONE IN YOUR FACE.
I WILL SAY AFTER COVERING 9-11
AND BEING IN NEW YORK ON THE
12TH YOU GET A DIFFERENT SENSE
TO A CERTAIN EXTENT.
YOU HAVE FAMILY MEMBERS THAT
WANT THE PERSON TO BE REMEMBERED
AND BE REMEMBERED IN A
PARTICULAR WAY THEY ARE TELLING
THE STORY.
>> BALANCED.
THAT'S WHAT WE ARE TRYING TO DO
HERE.
HOPEFULLY WE WILL ON SPECIAL
REPORT.
THAT'S IT FOR THE PANEL.
STAY TUNED TO FIND OUT WHAT ELSE
IS COMING TO WASHINGTON, D.C.
THIS HOLIDAY SEASON BESIDES
SANTA.
VICTOR! VICTOR!
I GOT YOUR
CAMPBELL'S CHUNKY SOUP.
MOM?
WHO'S MOM?
I'M THE GIANTS MASCOT.
THE GIANTS DON'T HAVE
A MASCOT!
OHHH! EAT UP!
NEW JAMMIN JERK CHICKEN SOUP
HAS TASTY PIECES OF CHICKEN
WITH RICE AND BEANS.
HMMM.
FOR GIANT HUNGER!
THANKS MOM!
SEE YA!
WHOAA...OOPS!
MOM?
I'M OK.
GRANDMA?
HI SWEETIE!
SHE OPERATES THE HEAD.
[ Male Announcer ]
CAMPBELL'S CHUNKY SOUP.
IT FILLS YOU UP RIGHT.
YOU HAVE A PLAN?
FIRST WE'RE GONNA
CHECK OUR BAGS FOR FREE,
THANKS
TO OUR EXPLORER CARD.
THEN, THE UNITED CLUB.
MY MOTR
WAS SO WRONG ABOUT YOU.
NEXT,
WE GET PRIORY BOARDING
ON OUR FLIGHT
I BOOKED WITH MILES.
ALL BECAUSE OF THE CARD.
AND ME.
OKAY, WHAT'S THE PLAN?
PLAN?
MM-HMM.
WE'RE ON VACATION.
THERE IS NO PLAN.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ] THE UNITED
MILEAGEPLUS EXPLORER CARD.
THE MILEAGE CARD
WITH SPECI PERKS ON UNITED.
GET IT AND YOU'RE IN.
A BODY AT REST
TENDS TO STAY AT REST...
WHILE A BODY IN MOTION
TENDS TO STAY IN MOTION.
STAYING ACTIVE CAN ACTUALLY
EASE ARTHRITIS SYMPTO.
BUT IF YOU HAVE ARTHRITIS,
STAYING ACTIVE
CAN BE DIFFICULT.
PRESCRIPTION CELEBREX
CAN HELP RELIEVE ARTHRITIS PAIN
SO YOUR BODY
CAN STAY IN MOTION.
BECAUSE JUST ONE
200MG CELEBREX A DAY
CAN PROVIDE 24 HOUR RELIEF
FOR MANY WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND INFLAMMATION.
PLUS, IN CLINICAL STUDIES,
CELEBREX IS PROVEN TO IMPROVE
DAILY PHYSICAL FUNCTION
SO MOVING IS EASIER.
CELEBREX CAN BE TAKEN WITH
OR WITHOUT FOOD.
AND IT'S NOT A NARCOTIC.
YOU AND YOUR DOCTOR
SHOULD BALANCE THE BENETS
WITH THEISKS.
ALL PRESCRIPTION NSAIDS,
LIKE CELEBREX, IBUPROFEN,
NAPROXEN, AND MELOXICAM
HAVE THE SAME
CARDIOVASCULAR WARNING.
THEY ALL MAY INCREASE
THE CHANCE
OF HEART ATTACK OR STROKE,
WHICH CAN LEAD TO DEATH.
THIS CHANCE INCREASES
IF YOU HAVE HEART DISEASE
RISK FACTORS
SUH AS HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE
OR WHEN NSAIDS ARE TAKEN
FOR LONG PERIODS.
NSAIDS, INCLUDING CELEBREX,
INCREASE THE CHANCE OF SERIOUS
SKIN OR ALLERGIC REACTIONS
OR STOMACH A INTESTINE
PROBLEMS,
SUCH AS BLEEDING AND CERS,
WHICH CAN OCCUR WITHOUT WARNING
AND MAY CAUSE DEATH.
PATIENTS ALSO TAKING ASPIRIN
AND THE ELDEY
ARE AT INCRSED RISK FOR
STOCH BLEEDING AND ULCERS.
DO NOT TAKE CELEBREX IF YOU'VE
HAD AN ASTHMA ATTACK, HIVES,
OR OTHER ALLERGIES TO ASPIRIN,
NSAIDS OR SULFONAMIDES.
GET HELP RIGHTWAY IF YOU HAVE
SWELNG OF THE FACE OR THROAT,
OR TROUBLE BREATHING.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
YOUR MEDICAL HISTORY
AND FIND AN ARTHRITIS TREATMENT
FOR YOU.
VISIT CELEBREX.COM AND ASK
YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT CELEBREX.
FOR A BODY IN MOTION.
>> FINALLY TONIGHT, THE HOLIDAYS
CAN BE EXHAUSTING.
NOW HERE IN WASHINGTON, D.C., WE
HAVE A NEW EXCITING ADDITION, OR
MAYBE NOT.
>> HE KNOWS IT'S A SPECIAL TIME
OF YEAR.
WE'VE BEEN LOOKING FORWARD TO IT
FOR MONTHS NUMBER EVERYWHERE YOU
GO, YOU CAN SEE THE TWINKLE IN
LITTLE