OBVIOUSLY WITH SOMETHING LIKE
THIS.
SO MANY LIVES LOST, YOUNG
LIVES LOST.
AT THE SAME TIME, IT'S BEEN
TRULY INSPIRING TO SEE THE WAY
THE COMMUNITY HAS COME
TOGETHER TO SUPPORT ONE
ANOTHER.
>> GRETA: IT'S BEEN JUST
TERRIBLE.
I FRANKLY DON'T KNOW WHAT TO
SAY TO ANYONE HERE, BUT THANKS
FOR JOINING US.
>> YES.
MY PLEASURE.
>> GRETA: THANK YOU FOR BEING
WITH US TONIGHT.
STAY WITH US THROUGHOUT THE
WEEKEND BR FOR LATEST ON THE
SCHOOL MASSACRE HERE IN
CONNECTICUT G NIGHT FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
NOW.
>> Bill: "THE O'REILLY FACTOR"
IS ON.
TONIGHT --
>> WE ALL HUDDLED AND I KEPT
HEARING THESE BOOMING NOISES.
>> FOX NEWS CONFIRMED THAT AS
MANY AS 27 PEOPLE ARE DEAD,
INCLUDING 20 CHILDREN.
>> Bill: UNSPEAKABLE EVIL IN
CONNECTICUT.
>> THE GYM TEACHERS DIRECTED TO
US TAKE AGAINST THE WALL AND
EVERYBODY STARTED TO PANIC.
>> Bill: DOZENS OF SCHOOL
CHILDREN MURDERED.
>> THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
>> Bill: TONIGHT WHAT HAPPENED?
HOW IT COULD HAPPEN AND CAN
AMERICA PREVENT THIS KIND OF
ATROCITY?
WE WILL HAVE A NUMBER OF
REPORTS.
>> HE'S TOUGH.
A LESSER PERSON WOULD HAVE
PLEADED GUILTY.
>> Bill: ALSO WILL PRESIDENT
OBAMA AND SECRETARY OF STATE
CLINTON DEMAND THE RELEASE OF
MARINE LANCE CORPORAL JON HAMMER
BEING HELD IN A MEXICAN PRISON
ON BOGUS CHARGES?
WE WILL CONTINUE OUR REPORTING
ON THIS DISTURBING STORY.
CAUTION.
YOU ARE ABOUT TO ENTER THE NO
SPIN ZONE.
"THE FACTOR" BEGINS RIGHT NOW.
>> Bill: HI.
I'M BILL O'REILLY.
THANKS FOR WATCHING US.
MASS MURDER IN CONNECTICUT,
UNSPEAKABLE EVIL ON DISPLAY.
THERE IS LITTLE ANYONE CAN SAY
WHEN 20 SCHOOL CHILDREN ARE
MURDERED.
THAT KIND OF THING DIMINISHES
THE ENTIRE COUNTRY AND DEEPLY
AFFECTS ALL GOOD PEOPLE.
HERE IS WHAT WE KNOW AT THIS
HOUR.
ABOUT 9:40 THIS MORNING AT THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
230-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA SHOT THE
PRINCIPAL DEAD AND ALSO KILLED A
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST.
THEN HE ENTERED TWO CLASSROOMS,
KILLING THE CHILDREN.
FOUR OTHER ADULTS DIED AS WELL.
LANZA HESS MOTHER, NANCY, WAS A
TEACHER AT THE SCHOOL AND HE
APPARENTLY MURDERED HER EARLIER
IN THE MORNING AT THE HOME THEY
SHARED.
RIGHT NOW THERE IS NO KNOWN
MOTIVE AND WE WON'T BE GETTING
ANY EXPLANATION FROM LANZA WHO
COMMITTED SUICIDE AT THE SCHOOL.
THIS IS THE WORST SCHOOL
SHOOTING EVER IN CONNECTICUT.
SECOND WORST IN THE UNITED
STATES BEHIND VIRGINIA TECH.
HERE ARE SOME SCENES IN THE
AFTERMATH OF THIS APPALLING
CRIME.
>> EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY
TODAY.
(SIRENS).
>> A CALL CAME IN TO DISPATCH.
POLICE OFFICERS AND RESOURCES
FROM ALL OVER THE STATE RACED TO
THAT AREA AS THEY CONVERGED ON
THE SCHOOL.
THE CHILDREN OBVIOUSLY WERE VERY
SHAKEN.
THEY WERE CRYING IN THE CLOSET.
WHEN THEY WERE LEAVING, THE
POLICE MADE THEM HOLD HANDS AND
TOLD THEM TO CLOSE THEIR EYES.
>> THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
>> THE GYM TEACHERS DIRECTED US
TO STAY AGAINST THE WALL.
EVERYBODY STARTED KIND OF
PANICS.
>> THERE IS NO WORDS.
IT'S SHEAR TERROR.
>> DOESN'T EVEN SEEM REAL.
IT JUST DOES NOT SEEM LIKE IT'S
EVEN POSSIBLE.
>> WE ALL HUDDLED AND I KEPT
HEARING THESE BOOMING NOISES.
>> I JUST SAW ALL THESE MOMS
NETWORKING, TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT'S GOING ON.
>> THE KIDS WERE TERRIFIED!
THEY WERE TERRIFIED.
THEY HAD JUST WITNESSED
SOMETHING AND THEY WERE
TERRIFIED.
>> MOST TRAUMATIZING THING I'VE
EVER BEEN TO.
>> MY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF
THE VICTIMS AND IN THE WORDS OF
SCRIPTURE, HEAL THE BROKEN
HEARTED AND BIND UP THEIR
WOUNDS.
>> Bill: THREE GUNS WERE FOUND
AT THE SCENE.
TWO PISTOLS AND A RIFLE.
POLICE SAY THEY WERE LEGALLY
PURCHASED AND REGISTERED TO
LANZA'S MOTHER WHO AGAIN WAS
APPARENTLY MUMPEDDED BY HIM.
WITH US NOW, GERALDO RIVERA.
BETWEEN US, WE PRETTY MUCH SEEN
WHAT THERE IS TO SEE IN THIS
WORLD, BUT THIS KIND OF EVIL HAS
GOT TO BE AT THE TOP OF THE
CHART.
>> YOU KNOW, BILL, I'VE BEEN EYE
TO EYE WITH CHARLES MANSON.
I'VE BEEN A WAR CORRESPONDENT
FOR SEVEN YEARS, I COVERED THE
WORSE ATROCITIES OF IRAQ AND
AFGHANISTAN.
THIS IS THE WORST THING EVER.
I HAVE A SCENE IN MY MIND THAT I
JUST CAN'T GET OUT OF MY MIND.
HE HAD THE THREE WEAPONS.
HE HAD THE GLOCK AND THE SIX
HOUR, BOTH .9 MILLIMETER, THE
223 BUSH MASTER.
IT'S UNCLEAR WHETHER OR NOT HE
USED IT.
MOST REPORTS ARE SUGGESTING HE
LEFT THAT ONE IN THE CAR, WHICH
MEANS HE WENT INTO THE SCHOOL,
GETS PAST SECURITY, GETS INTO
THE CLASSROOM, ONE OR TWO
CLASSROOMS AND STARTS FIRING AT
THE LITTLE CHILDREN.
AT SOME POINT HE HAS TO RUN OUT
OF AMMUNITION.
EVEN IF HE HAS EXTENDED
MAGAZINES, AT SOME POINT HE HAS
TO RELOAD.
SO THE SCENE I HAVE IN MY MIND
IS THESE BABIES, BETWEEN THE
AGES OF FIVE AND TEN, AS THIS
GROWNUP -- THESE ARE CHILDREN
WHO HAVE NEVER SEEN EVIL.
THESE ARE CHILDREN WHO ARE IN
THE FLOWER OF INNOCENCE.
HERE IS A GROWNUP DRESSED IN
CAMO AND BULLET PROOF VEST AND
HE'S GOT TWO HAND GUNS AND HE
STARTS KILLING THE CHILDREN AND
YOU CAN IMAGINE THE CHILDREN
SCREAMING AND THEN HE'S
RELOADING AND THERE IS THE DEAD
CHILDREN AND THERE IS THE
CHILDREN YET TO BE KILLED.
IN THIS MOMENT, JUST IMAGINE THE
TERROR BEFORE HE KILLS THEM.
IT IS SO UNCONSCIONABLE.
IT IS BEYOND DESCRIPTION.
IT IS SO EVIL DOESN'T DO IT.
IT DOESN'T EXPLAIN SUFFICIENTLY
THE WICKEDNESS, THE DEPRAVED
WRECKLESS INDIFFERENCE TO THE
LIVES OF THESE CHILDREN, JUST
SOMETHING AS THAT FATHER OF
FIVE, I CANNOT GET OUT MIFF
MIND.
>> Bill: NOBODY CAN.
THERE IS NO EXPLANATION FOR IT.
IT IS EVIL.
YOU WOULD ADMIT THAT'S WHAT IT
IS.
SO WHEN YOU LOOK AT THINGS LIKE
THIS THAT HAPPEN AND WHY THEY
HAPPEN SO MUCH IN THE UNITED
STATES, YOU KNOW.
WE SAW THE NORWEGIAN THING LAST
YEAR AND ALL OF THAT.
BUT IT'S A GOOD COUNTRY, BUT
THERE IS INSANITY.
THERE IS STRAIN OF INSANITY NOW
RUNNING THROUGH OUR COUNTRY.
WE'LL GET TO THAT A LITTLE
LATER.
YOU KNOW, YOU GO TO THE
CONCENTRATION CAMPS, YOU KNOW?
YOU BEEN THERE, RIGHT?
>> THAT'S WHAT IT MOST REMINDS
ME OF.
>> Bill: I'VE BEEN THERE.
>> A MINI HOLOCAUST.
>> Bill: GO TO THE CONCENTRATION
CAMPS AND GO TO CAMBODIA AND
THEY STILL HAVE THE SKULLS, IF
YOU WANT TO, YOU CAN GO SEE
THEM, AND YOU GO TO CHINA AND
YOU SEE WHAT'S HAPPENED IN
VARIOUS PLACES.
IT ALL COMES BACK TO ONE THING.
IT ALL COMES BACK TO THERE IS AN
EVIL IN THE UNIVERSE AND YOU
CAN'T STOP IT.
YOU CAN'T STOP IT.
WE HAVE TO DEAL WITH IT.
WE JUST HAVE TO DEAL WITH IT.
>> THIS YOUNG MAN, ADAM LANZA,
WOKE UP AND HE KILLED HIS
MOTHER.
WHY DID HE KILL HIS MOTHER?
WE DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE HE THOUGHT HIS MOTHER WAS
PAYING TOO MUCH ATTENTION TO THE
CHILDREN.
MAYBE IT WAS SOMETHING AS --
>> Bill: WE DON'T WANT TO
SPECULATE TONIGHT.
>> AS CRAZY AS THAT.
AFTER SHE'S DEAD, HE THEN DRIVES
TO HER CLASSROOM.
HOW BEST TO SAVAGE YOUR MOTHER
THAN TO GO AND KILL THE CHILDREN
SHE CARED FOR, THAT SHE
NURTURED, THAT SHE TAUGHT.
AND MY BROTHER CRAIG WAS THERE
ALL DAY.
HE SAW A SCENE WHERE ALL THE
PARENTS COLLECTED THEIR
CHILDREN, THE SURVIVING
CHILDREN, AND THE GOVERNOR AT
SOME POINT SAYS, THOSE WHO
HAVEN'T COLLECTED THEIR
CHILDREN, THERE ARE NO MORE
CHILDREN TO COLLECT.
THEY ARE INSIDE, THE FORENSICS
ARE STILL ONGOING.
THEY WERE AT THE FIRE HOUSE.
SO THERE WERE FAMILIES ARRIVING
LATE.
SOME COMING FROM OUT OF TOWN.
THE SCHOOL WAS ALMOST A MAGNET
BECAUSE IT WAS SO GOOD AND
PARENTS COMING DURING THE COURSE
OF THE AFTERNOON.
HE SAW A SCENE WHERE THE PARENTS
WERE TAKING THE CAR SEAT OUT OF
THE BACK SEAT AND PUTTING IT IN
THE TRUNK, NEVER TO BE USED
AGAIN.
THIS IS SOMETHING THAT -- I
MEAN, I DON'T THINK THERE IS A
PERSON LISTENING RIGHT NOW, A
PARENT WHO CAN'T JUST BE SO JUST
DEFEATED, DEFLATED, OUTRAGED,
SICKENED, DISGUSTED --
>> Bill: AND THE WORST PART OF
IT IS, WE CAN'T DO ANYTHING
ABOUT IT.
THERE IS NOTHING WE CAN DO.
>> THE OTHER BITTER IRONY IS
THAT THIS HEROIC PRINCIPAL, DAWN
HOCKSPRUNG IMPLEMENTED SECURITY
AT THE SCHOOL.
SHE PUT A BUZZER SYSTEM IN THE
SCHOOL THAT HE APPARENTLY BURST
THROUGH TO GET TO THE --
>> Bill: IF HIS MOM TAUGHT
THERE, THEY KNEW HIM AND HE KNEW
HOW TO GET INTO THE SCHOOL.
>> I WANT AN ARMED COP AT EVERY
SCHOOL.
I REMEMBER THERE WERE TWO SCHOOL
SHOOTINGSINGS AND WERE THERE WEE
AMISH KIDS IN PENNSYLVANIA.
AND THEN I SAID, WE HAVE TO
PROTECT THESE CHILDREN AS IF
THEY WERE GOLD.
AS IF THEY WERE THE MATERIAL YOU
USE FOR ATOM BOMBS, YOU HAVE TO
PROTECT THE CHILDREN.
>> Bill: I KNOW THAT ALL OVER
THE UNITED STATES RIGHT NOW,
THAT, WHAT YOU JUST SAID, IS
BEING DISCUSSED.
IN HEIGHTENED SECURITY FOR ALL
THE KIDS.
ALL RIGHT.
THANKS FOR COMING IN.
WE APPRECIATE IT.
HE'S GOT SPECIAL REPORTS ALL
WEEKEND ON SATURDAY AND SUNDAY.
NEXT ON THE RUNDOWN, WE WILL GO
TO THE SCENE OF THE CRIME IN
CONNECTICUT AND TALK WITH FOX
CORRESPONDENT RICK LEVENTHAL, AS
WELL AS WITH A THIRD GRADER WHO
SURVIVED TODAY'S MASS MURDER.
"THE FACTOR" WILL BE BACK IN A
MOMENT
YOU WON'T TAKE MY LIFE.
YOU WON'T TAKE OUR FUTURE.
AIDS AFFECTS US ALL.
EVEN BABIES.
CHEVRON IS WORKING TO STOP
MOTHER-TO-CHILD TRANSMISSION.
OUR EMPLOYEES AND THEIR FAMILIES
ARE PART OF THE FIGHT.
AND WE'RE WINNING.
AT CHEVRON NIGERIA, WE HAVEN'T
HAD A REPORTED CASE IN 12EARS.
AIDS IS STRONG.
BUT WE ARE STRONGER.
AND AIDS...
♪
AIDS IS GOING TO LOSE.
TO COME HOME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE...
SADLY, THEIR BROTHER'S
WHITE CHRISTMAS
JUST GOT "BLACKED OUT."
[ Brother ]
BUT IT'S THE FAMILY PARTY!
REALLY JINGLES YOUR BELLS,
DOESN'T IT?
MY GIFT TO YOU!
THE Capital One Venture Card!
FOR ANY FLIGHT, ANY TIME!
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE!
HOW ILLUMINATING.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
LET ME GUESS, AM
ON THE NAUGHTY LIST AGAIN?
HO HO HO!
LET ME GUESS, AM
ON THE NAUGHTY LIST AGAIN?
Is bigger than we think ...
Sometimelike the flu.fer from
With aches, fever and chills-
the flu's a really big deal.
So why treat it like
it's a little cold?
There's something
that works differently
than over-the-counter
remedies.
Prescription TAMIFLU attacks
the flu virus at its source.
So don't wait. Call your
doctor right away.
TAMIFLU is prescription
medicine for treating the flu
in adults and children
one year and older
whose flu symptoms started
within the last two days.
Before taking TAMIFLU tell your
doctor if you're pregnant,
nursing. have serious
health conditions,
or take other medicines.
If you develop an allergic
reaction, a severe rash,
or signs of unusual behavior,
stop taking TAMIFLU and call
your doctor immediately.
Children and adolescents in
particular may be at an
increased risk
of seizures, confusion
or abnormal behavior.
The most common
side effects are
mild to moderate nausea
and vomiting.
The flu comes on fast,
so ask your
doctor about TAMIFLU.
Prescription for flu.
>> Bill: CONTINUING WITH "THE
FACTOR"'S COVERAGE.
JOINING US FROM THE SCENE OF THE
CRIME, FOX NEWS CORRESPONDENT
RICK LEVENTHAL.
WHAT'S GOING ON NOW?
LOT OF REPORTERS OBVIOUSLY FROM
ALL OVER THE WORLD HAVE
DESCENDED UPON A SMALL
CONNECTICUT TOWN.
WHAT ARE THEY TRYING TO
ACCOMPLISH THIS EVENING?
>> BILL, OBVIOUSLY EVERYONE IS
TRYING TO GET THE LATEST
INFORMATION AND TRY TO PIECE
TOGETHER WHAT HAPPENED HERE
TODAY.
I CAN TELL YOU THAT I'VE SPOKEN
WITH A NUMBER OF FEDERAL
INVESTIGATORS, ONE OF WHOM, A
SEASONED INVESTIGATOR, ONE OF
THE BIGGEST, TOUGHEST GUYS I
KNOW, AND HE WAS SHOCKED AS HE
RELATED THE NEWS TO ME.
THE DETAILS OF THIS HORRIFIC
CRIME.
WHEN YOU HEAR FROM LAW
ENFORCEMENT THE HORROR AT WHAT
TRANSPIRED, IT REALLY BRINGS IT
HOME.
THE FACT THAT THIS KID, WOULD
SHOOT HIS OWN MOTHER IN HER HOME
AND THEN DRIVE TO THE SCHOOL
WHERE SHE APPARENTLY WORKED AND
SLAUGHTERED CHILDREN, IT'S
ALMOST TOO HORRIFIC TO BELIEVE.
>> Bill: WE GET OUR REPORTS FROM
LAW ENFORCEMENT THAT HUNDREDS OF
SHOTS WERE FIRED BY THIS GUY AND
HE HAD PLANNED IT OUT.
I MEAN, OBVIOUSLY HE HAD TAKEN
THREE WEAPONS WITH HIM.
BUT THERE IS NO MUCH ELSE KNOWN
OTHER THAN HE'S A MASS MURDERER,
HE DIDN'T CARE ABOUT ANYBODY,
OBVIOUSLY HIS MOTHER, CHILDREN,
NOTHING MATTER TO DO HIM AT ALL.
DO THE ACTS THAT YOU TALKED TO,
DID THEY DESCRIBE THE INSIDE OF
THE SCHOOL?
DID THEY TELL YOU ANYTHING THAT
SPECIFICALLY HAPPENED?
>> WELL, WE'VE HEARD FROM LAW
ENFORCEMENT JUST IN GENERAL
TERMS HOW AWFUL THE SCENE IS.
IT'S GOING TO TAKE THEM DAYS TO
PROCESS THAT SCENE.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER IS INSIDE
THE SCHOOL AT THIS HOUR
ATTEMPTING TO WORK THROUGH THE
IDENTIFICATION OF THE BODIES,
INCLUDING THOSE 18 CHILDREN
STILL IN THE SCHOOL.
THAT COULD BE FINISHED, THEY
HOPE BY TOMORROW, BILL.
BUT WE HAVE ALSO LEARNED THROUGH
LAW ENFORCEMENT SOURCES THAT THE
BROTHER OF THIS SHOOTER, RYAN
LANZA, WAS ORIGINALLY IDENTIFIED
AS THE SHOOTER, MAYBE BECAUSE
HIS YOUNGER BROTHER WAS CARRYING
HIS I.D
HE HAS SPOKEN WITH FEDERAL
AUTHORITIES AND DESCRIBED AS
VERY COOPERATIVE.
HE'S TELLING FEDERAL AUTHORITIES
THAT HE BELIEVES HIS BROTHER HAD
DEVELOPED MENTAL PROBLEMS AND
POSSIBLY AUTISM, AND THE BOY'S
FATHER ALSO SAID TO BE
COOPERATING WITH FEDERAL
AUTHORITIES IN NEW JERSEY, BEING
QUESTIONED, TRYING TO SHED LIGHT
ON THIS KID'S MENTAL STATE AND
WHAT MAY HAVE SET HIM OFF.
>> Bill: ALL RIGHT.
SO THEY HAVE THE FATHER AND THE
BROTHER WHO ARE OBVIOUSLY TRYING
TO EXPLAIN TO AUTHORITIES THE
CONDITION OF THE DEAD MURDERER.
WHEN YOU COVER A STORY LIKE
THIS, THERE IS A LOT OF CHAOS
AND THERE IS A LOT OF
MISREPORTING, AS YOU JUST
MENTIONED, THE KID RYAN, WE JUST
SAW, THE BROTHER, WAS INITIALLY
TIED IN TO THE CRIME, BUT NOW
HE'S BEEN TOTALLY EXONERATED,
RIGHT?
THERE IS JUST ONE SHOOTER.
THEY BELIEVE IT'S ONE MAN WHO
DID THESE HORRIBLE THINGS.
IS THAT CORRECT?
>> CORRECT.
YEAH.
BILL, YOU CAN UNDERSTAND, IN THE
AFTERMATH OF A MAJOR INCIDENT
LIKE THIS, THERE IS A LOT OF
CONFUSION.
IN THIS CASE, IF THE SHOOTER WAS
CARRYING AN IDENTIFICATION, THEN
THAT WOULD LEAD INVESTIGATORS TO
PREVIOUS THAT WAS HIM.
APPARENTLY IT WAS HIS BROTHER.
HIS OLDER BROTHER.
THIS KID IS 20.
HIS BROTHER IS 24.
HE MAY HAVE HAD HIS I.D. ON HIM
FOR PURPOSES OF WHO KNOWS?
ALCOHOL.
LEAR.NOWS?
THE SHOOTER WHO IS NOW DEAD, WAS
CARRYING HIS BROTHER'S I.D
THAT'S THE I.D. THEY FOUND ON
HIM.
AND HIS BROTHER AND THE FATHER
LIVE IN NEW JERSEY, NOT CLOSE TO
THE SCENE.
ALL RIGHT.
RICK.
WE APPRECIATE IT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
DIRECTLY AHEAD, A THIRD GRADER
SURVIVES THE MURDER.
WE WILL TALK WITH HER AND HER
MOTHER.
LATER PRESSURE GROWING ON MEXICO
TO RELEASE A FORMER MARINE THEY
PUT IN PRISON ON BOGUS CHARGES.
THOSE REPORTS AFTER THESE
MESSAGE
There is no
mass-produced human.
Every human being
is unique.
And there is one store
that recognizes it.
The Sleep Nuer Store.
The only place in the
world you'll find the
extraordinarily comfortable
Sleep Number Experience.
An exclusive collection of
innovations that totally
individualize your sleep.
Perfectly comfortable
pillows that adjust to
your size and shape.
Temperature-balancing
bedding.
Dual warmth comforters.
All designed around the
Sleep Number Bed: A bed
with dual-air technology
that allows you to adjust
to the support your
body needs.
Each of your bodies.
In the name of human
individuality: The Sleep
Number Collection.
Discover how our sleep
professionals can
individualize your sleep
experience.
Exclusively at one of our 400
Sleep Number Stores nationwide.
Sleep Number.
Comfort Individualized.
This holiday season, give
the gift that's magical:
the innovative AirFit
adjustable pillow at
special 30% savings.
>> Bill: IN THE IMPACT SEGMENT,
NO WORDS CAN CONSOLE THE
FAMILIES OF THE DEAD CHILDREN IN
CONNECTICUT.
NO WORDS.
THERE WERE MORE THAN 600
CHILDREN IN THE SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL TODAY.
THE SURVIVORS WILL CARRY THIS
CRIME WITH THEM FOREVER.
JOINING US FROM NEWTOWN, BRENDA
AND HER EIGHT-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER,
SOPHIA, THIRD GRADER AT THE
SCHOOL.
SOPHIA, YOU OKAY TONIGHT?
YOU ALL RIGHT?
>> YES.
>> Bill: CAN YOU TELL US WHAT
YOU SAW TODAY, WHAT HAPPENED TO
YOU AT SCHOOL TODAY?
>> WELL, WE WERE AT MORNING
MEETING AND THEN WE HEARD THESE
KNOCKING SOUNDS AND THEN MISS
MARTIN, SHE CLOSED THE DOOR AND
LOCKED IT AND THEN TOLD US TO GO
IN THE CORNER AND THEN WE WERE
LIKE SHAKING AND EVERYBODY WAS
ALL SQUISHED.
>> Bill: DID YOU KNOW WHAT WAS
HAPPENING OUTSIDE YOUR
CLASSROOM?
DID THE TEACHER TELL YOU
ANYTHING?
>> NO.
>> Bill: SO YOU WERE JUST SCARED
'CAUSE SHE DIDN'T KNOW AND YOU
KNEW THE TEACHER WAS CONCERNED?
>> YES.
>> Bill: HOW DID YOU GET OUT OF
THE SCHOOL, SOPHIA?
>> WELL, SOMEONE WAS KNOCKING
DONE THE DOOR AND OUR ASSISTANT,
SHE LOOKED OUT THE DOOR AND IT
WAS THE POLICE TO TELL US TO
COME OUT.
SO WE WENT OUT AND WENT TO THE
FIRE HOUSE.
>> Bill: OKAY.
DID YOU TALK TO YOUR DAUGHTER
ABOUT THIS?
DOES SHE UNDERSTAND IT?
I MEAN, THIS IS SO TRAUMATIC FOR
EVERYONE.
ADULTS ARE BREAKING DOWN.
HOW IS SOPHIA DEALING WITH IT
WITH YOU?
>> I THINK SHE'S STILL NUMB.
SHE HAS HER FAMILY AROUND HER.
MY SISTER CAME UP, SO I THINK
THE GRAVITY OF THE SITUATION
HASN'T HIT HER YET.
SHE WASN'T REALLY EXPOSED TO ANY
OF THE BODIES OR ANYTHING.
THEY TOOK HER OUT A BACK DOOR.
>> Bill: THAT'S GOOD.
>> THEN WENT TO THE FIRE HOUSE.
>> Bill: DID YOU KNOW ANY OF THE
CHILDREN WHO WERE KILLED?
DID SOPHIA KNOW THEM?
I THINK THEY WERE YOUNGER,
RIGHT?
>> THEY WERE SUPPOSEDLY IN
KINDERGARTEN.
WE HAVEN'T BEEN TOLD ANY OF THE
CHILDREN'S NAMES.
SO I DON'T KNOW.
I DO KNOW THAT MY FRIENDS THAT
I'VE TALKED TO, THEIR CHILDREN
ARE SAFE.
I MADE SURE OF THAT.
ANYBODY I SAW IN THE FIRE HOUSE,
I HUGGED THEM.
AND I SAID DO YOU HAVE YOUR
BABIES?
AND THEY SAID YES, WE'RE OKAY.
IT WASN'T UNTIL LATER WHEN -- GO
AHEAD.
>> Bill: SANDY HOOK IS A VERY,
VERY CALM PLACE, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, A BEAUTIFUL SUBURB.
>> OH, YEAH.
>> Bill: NO VIOLENCE TO SPEAK
OF.
>> SAFE.
>> Bill: THIS WOULD BE THE LAST
PLACE ON EARTH YOU WOULD THINK
AT THAT THIS WOULD HAPPEN.
WHERE WERE YOU WHEN YOU HEARD
ABOUT THIS AND WHAT WAS YOUR
REACTION?
>> OKAY.
I WAS HOME DOING MY CHRISTMAS
CARDS ON-LINE AND I RECEIVED A
PHONE CALL FROM THE SCHOOL
SUPERINTENDENT THAT WE USUALLY
GET IF THERE IS GOING TO BE AN
EARLY DISMISSAL, YOU KNOW,
SOMETHING OF THAT SORT, SAYING
THAT THERE WAS A SHOOTING IN
NEWTOWN AND THAT THE SCHOOLS
WERE ON LOCKDOWN.
BUT SHE DID NOT SAY THAT THERE
WAS A SHOOTING AT ONE OF THE
SCHOOLS.
SO I WASN'T THAT CONCERNED UNTIL
I RECEIVED A TEXT FROM -- I
THINK IT WAS A.P. NEWS ON MY
PHONE SAYING THAT THERE WAS A
SHOOTING IN THE SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL ON DICKINSON.
THAT'S WHERE MY DAUGHTER
ATTENDS, SO I JUMPED IN THE CAR.
I WENT TO THE SCHOOL.
THERE WAS ALREADY PARENTS THERE
CRYING AND I SAW A FRIEND OF
MINE.
I SAID WHAT HAPPENED?
AND THEY WERE HYSTERICAL THAT
THEY CARRIED OUT A LITTLE GIRL
AND SHE LOOKED LIKE SHE WAS
DEAD.
I PANICKED.
BUT LUCKILY I SAW MY DAUGHTER
RIGHT AWAY COMING WITH HER
TEACHER, 'CAUSE THEY STARTED
WALKING THE KIDS FROM THE SCHOOL
TO THE FIRE HOUSE, WHICH IS
ALMOST ADJACENT TO THE SCHOOL.
>> Bill: BY ALL ACCOUNTS, THE
SCHOOL HANDLED THE SITUATION
WELL AND THE POLICE AND THE
AUTHORITIES DID A GOOD JOB.
IS THAT WHAT YOU SAW?
>> YES.
ABSOLUTELY.
>> Bill: SO EVERYBODY WAS
REASSURED QUICKLY?
YOU SAY YOU PANICKED, BUT
EVERYTHING WAS CONTAINED.
>> THE CHILDREN WERE BEING
ORDERLY, TAKEN TO THE FIRE
HOUSE.
THEY WENT INTO A LARGE ROOM.
THERE WAS A LOT OF CRYING.
BUT THE TEACHERS SEEM TO KEEP
THE KIDS CALM AND WE KEPT EVERY
CLASSROOM WAS KEPT TOGETHER, SO
THE TEACHER KNEW WHERE HER KIDS
WERE.
AS THE PARENTS CAME IN, YOU
KNOW, SHE'S OVER HERE, YOU KNOW.
SHE'S OKAY.
WE HAD NO IDEA THE GRAVITY OF
THE SITUATION UNTIL LATER ON
WHEN I CAME HOME AND I HEARD THE
NEWS.
I HEARD THAT THE PRINCIPAL WAS
SHOT AND THE LITTLE GIRL THAT I
WAS TOLD THAT WAS TAKEN OUT
BLOODY.
BUT WE HAD NO IDEA THAT THERE
WOULD BE 20 SOME ODD PEOPLE
KILLED.
>> Bill: DID YOU KNOW THIS
TEACHER WHOSE SON DID THIS
ALLEGEDLY AND WOUND UP DEAD?
DID YOU KNOW HER?
>> I NEVER HEARD HER NAME
BEFORE.
I HAVE OLDER CHILDREN.
THEY DON'T KNOW THE BOYS.
SHE'S NOT LISTED ON THE
DIRECTORY IN SCHOOL AS A
KINDERGARTEN TEACHER.
I DO KNOW THAT THEY STARTED A
PRESCHOOL HERE THIS YEAR.
SO I DON'T KNOW IF SHE WAS A
PRESCHOOL TEACHER.
>> Bill: BUT YOU DON'T KNOW HER.
OKAY.
>> NO.
>> Bill: ALL RIGHT.
SOPHIA, WE APPRECIATE YOU
TELLING US YOUR STORY AND WE
HOPE YOU'RE OKAY AND MISS
LABINSKI, IF YOU NEED ANYTHING,
YOU LET US KNOW.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I'M SORRY YOU HAD TO GO THROUGH
THIS.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Bill: PLENTY MORE AS "THE
FACTOR" MOVES ALONG THIS
EVENING.
EVIL PEOPLE, CAN WE PROTECT
OURSELVES AGAINST THEM?
WE'LL TALK WITH TWO MENTAL
HEALTH WORKERS.
AND THEN MARINE CORPORAL JON
HAMMER STILL IN A MEXICAN
PRISON.
WE'RE TRYING HARD TO GET HIM
OUT.
WE HAVE HOPE YOU STAY TUNED FOR
THOSE
[ Male Announcer ]
KIDS GROW UP IN NO TIME...
MARIE CALLENDER'S
TURKEY BREAST WITH STUFFING
IS A GREAT REASON TO SLOW DOWN.
CREAMY MASH POTATOES,
HOMESTYLE GRAVY
AND 320 CALORIES.
MARIE CALLENDER'S.
IT'S TIME TO SAVOR.
Neural speeds
increasing to 4G LTE.
Brain upgrading to a quad-core
processor.
Predictive intelligence
with Google Now complete.
Introducing DROID DNA by HTC.
It's not an upgrade
to your phone.
It's an upgrade to yourself.
A BODY AT REST
TENDS TO STAY AT REST...
WHILE A BODY IN MOTION
TENDS TO STAY IN MOTION.
STAYING ACTIVE CAN ACTUALLY
EASE ARTHRITIS SYMPTO.
BUT IF YOU HAVE ARTHRITIS,
STAYING ACTIVE
CAN BE DIFFICULT.
PRESCRIPTION CELEBREX
CAN HELP RELIEVE ARTHRITIS PAIN
SO YOUR BODY
CAN STAY IN MOTION.
BECAUSE JUST ONE
200MG CELEBREX A DAY
CAN PROVIDE 24 HOUR RELIEF
FOR MANY WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND INFLAMMATION.
PLUS, IN CLINICAL STUDIES,
CELEBREX IS PROVEN TO IMPROVE
DAILY PHYSICAL FUNCTION
SO MOVING IS EASIER.
CELEBREX CAN BE TAKEN WITH
OR WITHOUT FOOD.
AND IT'S NOT A NARCOTIC.
YOU AND YOUR DOCTOR
SHOULD BALANCE THE BENETS
WITH THEISKS.
ALL PRESCRIPTION NSAIDS,
LIKE CELEBREX, IBUPROFEN,
NAPROXEN, AND MELOXICAM
HAVE THE SAME
CARDIOVASCULAR WARNING.
THEY ALL MAY INCREASE
THE CHANCE
OF HEART ATTACK OR STROKE,
WHICH CAN LEAD TO DEATH.
THIS CHANCE INCREASES
IF YOU HAVE HEART DISEASE
RISK FACTORS
SUH AS HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE
OR WHEN NSAIDS ARE TAKEN
FOR LONG PERIODS.
NSAIDS, INCLUDING CELEBREX,
INCREASE THE CHANCE OF SERIOUS
SKIN OR ALLERGIC REACTIONS
OR STOMACH A INTESTINE
PROBLEMS,
SUCH AS BLEEDING AND CERS,
WHICH CAN OCCUR WITHOUT WARNING
AND MAY CAUSE DEATH.
PATIENTS ALSO TAKING ASPIRIN
AND THE ELDEY
ARE AT INCRSED RISK FOR
STOCH BLEEDING AND ULCERS.
DO NOT TAKE CELEBREX IF YOU'VE
HAD AN ASTHMA ATTACK, HIVES,
OR OTHER ALLERGIES TO ASPIRIN,
NSAIDS OR SULFONAMIDES.
GET HELP RIGHTWAY IF YOU HAVE
SWELNG OF THE FACE OR THROAT,
OR TROUBLE BREATHING.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
YOUR MEDICAL HISTORY
AND FIND AN ARTHRITIS TREATMENT
FOR YOU.
VISIT CELEBREX.COM AND ASK
YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT CELEBREX.
FOR A BODY IN MOTION.
>> Bill: UNRESOLVE PROBLEM
SEGMENT, HOW SHOULD WE PROCESS
EVIL AND PROTECT OURSELVES FROM
IT?
JOINING US FROM BOSTON,
PSYCHOTHERAPIST DR. KAREN RUSKIN
AND KANSAS CITY, DR. RUSSELL,
FORENSIC SCIENTIST AND ATTORNEY.
COULD EVIL LIKE THIS EVER BE
DEALT WITH EFFECTIVELY,
DR. RUSSELL?
>> WELL, BILL, YOU CAN'T
ELIMINATE IT, BUT YOU CAN
MINIMIZE IT BETTER THAN WE'RE
DOING.
NOT JUST BY ENHANCED SECURITY
PRACTICES.
A COUPLE BIG THINGS, BILL, ONE
IS WE CAN RETHINK OUR
DEINSTITUTIONALIZATION POLICY
WHERE BY FAR TOO OFTEN WE
ACTUALLY SHOW MORE COMPASSION
FOR AN OBVIOUSLY DANGEROUSLY
TROUBLED INDIVIDUAL THAN WE DO
FOR EVERYBODY IN THE SOCIETY
THAT THAT PERSON MAY HARM.
AND SECONDLY, WE CAN GET BACK TO
BEING THE KIND OF A CULTURE IN
WHICH KIDS GROW UP GETTING LOTS
OF MESSAGES AT HOME, SCHOOL,
CHURCH, EVERYWHERE ABOUT BEING
PART OF SOMETHING LARGER THAN
THEMSELVES.
THINKING ABOUT THE IMPACTS OF
THEIR ACTIONS ON OTHERS BECAUSE
WE'VE BECOME COARSENED AND
CALLUS TO THE POINT THAT A KID
CAN GROW UP IN THIS SOCIETY AND
NOT NECESSARILY INTERNALIZE THE
KIND OF DISGUST THAT YOU AND I
FEEL, THIS VISCERAL DISGUST FOR
THE KIND OF DISREGARD FOR HUMAN
LIFE THAT WE SAW TODAY.
>> Bill: DR. RUSKIN, IT SEEMS TO
ME THAT THERE IS CASUAL VIOLENCE
AND VERY EXPLICIT VIOLENCE ON
DISPLAY MORE THAN EVER BEFORE
AND THAT'S, OF COURSE, THANKS TO
THE INTERNET.
I'M NOT SURE WHETHER THIS IS
HAVING AN UNINTENDED CONSEQUENCE
ON A GENERATION OF AMERICANS.
IT'S HARD TO QUANTIFY THAT.
BUT CERTAINLY THE CASUAL
VIOLENCE IS ON DISPLAY FAR MORE
THAN ANY OTHER TIME IN HISTORY.
AM I WRONG?
>> I WOULDN'T YOU ARE NOT WRONG.
AND WE CAN'T IGNORE THE FACT
THAT OUR ENVIRONMENT ABSOLUTELY
AFFECTS US.
WE MUST VIEW THINGS
SYSTEMICALLY.
WE ARE A SYSTEM L IT'S
TELEVISION, WHETHER IT'S PARENTS
BEING TOO BUSY TO SPEND QUALITY
TIME WITH THEIR KIDS, WHETHER A
KID IS HURTING AND ANOTHER CHILD
IS MEAN ABOUT THAT, WHETHER
TEACHERS ARE NOT NOTICING,
WHETHER PARENTS ARE NOT NOTICING
WHAT'S HAPPENING WITH THE
EMOTIONAL WELL-BEING OF THEIR
KIDS.
EVERYTHING AFFECTS EVERYTHING.
THE VIOLENCE THAT WE'RE
EXPERIENCING IS SYSTEMIC AND WE
NEED TO PUT A STOP TO IT BY
EVERYBODY PLAYING A ROLE,
PARENTS, VERY IMPORTANT.
I BELIEVE THAT'S WHERE IT ALL
STARTS, AT A YOUNG AGE.
>> Bill: ALL RIGHT.
SO BUT IT'S ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE TO
LEGISLATE GOOD PARENTING,
DR. RUSSELL.
THAT'S A PROBLEM ON ALMOST EVERY
SOCIOLEVEL THAT WE HAVE IN
AMERICA.
I MEAN, FAMILIES FALL APART.
FATHERS ABANDON CHILDREN,
MOTHERS ABUSE CHILDREN, WHATEVER
IT MAY BE, THEN THE CHILDREN
SUFFER.
SO IN A FREE SOCIETY, YOU'RE
ALWAYS GOING TO HAVE
DYSFUNCTIONAL PEOPLE AND YOU'RE
ALWAYS GOING TO HAVE EVIL.
ALWAYS.
I DON'T THINK A LOT OF PEOPLE
UNDERSTAND -- MY MOTHER, FOR
EXAMPLE, DOESN'T UNDERSTAND
EVIL.
WHEN I WOULD TELL HER, HEY, MOM,
I WAS IN EL SALVADOR AND I SAW
NUNS GET SHOT IN THE BACK OF THE
HEAD, SHE ALMOST COULDN'T
PROCESS IT.
SHE COULDN'T PROCESS IT.
YOU KNOW.
AND I DON'T KNOW WHETHER WE
AMERICANS REALLY UNDERSTAND THE
CONCEPT OF EVIL.
>> YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT THAT
IT EXISTS.
IT AND I CAN TELL YOU THAT THERE
ABSOLUTELY ARE PEOPLE, THEY MAY
NOT BE MENTALLY HEALTHY, THEY'RE
SANE AND THEY CHOOSE TO HURT
OTHERS JUST BECAUSE THEY WANT TO
AND WE HAVE TO WRAP OUR MINDS
AROUND THAT AND YOU'RE RIGHT, WE
CAN'T MAKE EVERYBODY PARENT THE
WAY THAT THEY SHOULD.
SOCIETY IS NOT SQUANDER CHANCES
WHEN WE GET THEM TO INTERVENE
BECAUSE THE PERSON HAS GIVEN US
REASON TO, HAS SHOWN A
PROPENSITY TO BE DANGEROUS.
I PREDICTED IN THIS THING, WE'RE
GOING TO FIND OUT THERE WERE
SIGNS ALL OVER THE PLACE.
>> Bill: THERE USUALLY ARE.
THERE ARE USUALLY SIGNS.
ALTHOUGH A TED BUNDY, THE SERIAL
KILLER, TRACKED THAT GUY ALL
OVER THE UNITED STATES,
NOBODY -- I TALKED TO HIS
MOTHER.
NOBODY THOUGHT THAT HE WAS A
MONSTER WHO WOULD LOOK A WOMAN
IN THE EYE AND THEN CUT HER
THROAT BECAUSE HE CAME ACROSS AS
THIS PREPPY, REGULAR GUY.
BUT SOCIOPATHS AND NARE CITY
CYSTS, I THINK THIS IS GROWING
IN OUR SOCIETY.
I THINK THAT THIS DISEASE, THIS
MENTAL ILLNESS OF SOCIOPATHY IS
GROWING AND I DON'T KNOW WHY.
>> YOU KNOW, THERE IS A
DIFFERENCE BETWEEN THE
PSYCHOPATH AND THE SOCIOPATH.
THE PSYCHOPATH, THEY DON'T CARE
EVEN IF IT'S THEIR FAMILY THAT
THEY'RE HURTING.
THERE IS NO REMORSE.
THERE IS NO GUILT.
WHEREAS A SOCIOPATH MAY OR MAY
NOT FEEL GUILTY OVER HURT AGO
FAMILY MEMBER, BUT THEY SURE AS
HECK DON'T FEEL GUILTY ABOUT
HURTING SOMEBODY ELSE.
AND THE PSYCHOPATH CAN APPEAR
VERY LOVELY TO OTHERS, WHEREAS
THIS SOCIOPATH OFTEN YOU CAN
TELL THAT THERE IS A
DISTURBANCE, AND I BELIEVE THAT
IN OUR CULTURE, AS WE HAVE
BECOME SO SELF-ABSORBED AND
SELF-TITLED THAT WE DESERVEVE LE
NOT TO FEEL HURT, I DESERVE TO
HAVE MONEY.
I DESERVE HAVE A JOB.
YES, YES.
EVERYBODY DESERVES.
BUT THE FACT IS, WE CAN NOT
CONTROL THE CARDS THAT ARE DEALT
TO US.
SO RATHER WE MUST WORK HARD
EVERY DAY IN OUR MENTAL HEALTH
AND WELLNESS AND WELL-BEING AND
IF WE'RE NOT FEELING WELL, WE,
WE, WE, I MUST TAKE OWNERSHIP OF
MY OWN BEHAVIOR AND SEEK OUT
HELP.
>> Bill: THAT'S A MATURE MIND.
YOUR POINT ABOUT WE ALL FEEL WE
DESERVE ALL THIS AND IF WE DON'T
GET IT, SOME OF US GO INTO A
RAGE AND SOME OF US LOSE IT AND
START TO INFLICT DAMAGE I THINK
A GOOD ONE.
BUT ONLY A MATURE MIND WILL SAY,
I NEED HELP.
DOCTOR, I'M GOING TO LEAVE YOU
THE LAST WORD IN KANSAS CITY.
PEOPLE WATCHING TONIGHT, THERE
IS NO SOLUTION TO EVIL.
WE JUST HAVE TO RECOGNIZE IT, I
THINK.
>> TWO THINGS.
DON'T CALL IT AN ILLNESS BECAUSE
THIS, WHAT WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
TONIGHT TRANSCENDS PSYCHOLOGY.
EVERYBODY WATCHING TONIGHT HAS
TO DECIDE WHAT TO CALL IT.
I CALL IT EVIL.
YOU CALL IT EVIL.
THE OTHER THING TO KEEP IN MIND,
YOU DO A LOT ON THE CULTURE WAR.
WHEN YOU HAVE AN ENTIRE CULTURE
THAT'S DRIFTING IN A DIRECTION,
YOU'RE BOUND TO HAVE THOSE
PEOPLE WHO ARE OUT THERE ON THE
FRINGES OF IT ANYWAY DRIFTING
EVEN FARTHER OUT OF THE BOUNDS.
>> Bill: ALLALL RIGHT.
THANKS VERY MUCH.
WHEN WE COME BACK, FORMER MARINE
UNJUSTLY IMPRISONED IN MEXICO.
WILL THE OBAMA ADMINISTRATION BE
ABLE TO GET HIM OUT OF JAIL?
WE'LL HAVE THE VERY LATEST ON A
VERY TROUBLING STORY.
THEN WE WILL GO BACK TO THE
CRIME SCENE IN CONNECTICUT.
THE LATEST BREAKING NEWS WITH
BILL HEMMER AND "THE FACTOR"
WILL RETURN AFTER THESE
ANNOUNCEMENT
Music: "Make Someone Happy"
♪It's so important to make
someone happy.♪
It's so important to make
meone happy.♪
♪Make just one someone happy
♪And you will be happy too.
Is bigger than we think ...
Sometimelike the flu.fer from
With aches, fever and chills-
the flu's a really big deal.
So why treat it like
it's a little cold?
There's something
that works differently
than over-the-counter
remedies.
Prescription TAMIFLU attacks
the flu virus at its source.
So don't wait. Call your
doctor right away.
TAMIFLU is prescription
medicine for treating the flu
in adults and children
one year and older
whose flu symptoms started
within the last two days.
Before taking TAMIFLU tell your
doctor if you're pregnant,
nursing. have serious
health conditions,
or take other medicines.
If you develop an allergic
reaction, a severe rash,
or signs of unusual behavior,
stop taking TAMIFLU and call
your doctor immediately.
Children and adolescents in
particular may be at an
increased risk
of seizures, confusion
or abnormal behavior.
The most common
side effects are
mild to moderate nausea
and vomiting.
The flu comes on fast,
so ask your
doctor about TAMIFLU.
Prescription for flu.
>> Bill: THANKS FOR STAYING WITH
US.
I'M BILL O'REILLY.
WE'LL GO BACK TO CONNECTICUT
SHORTLY.
BUT FIRST IN "THE FACTOR"
FOLLOW-UP TONIGHT, THE TALKING
POINTS MEMO.
MEXICO INSULTING EVERY SINGLE
AMERICAN CITIZEN.
27-YEAR-OLD JON HAMMER, FORMER
MARINE LANCE CORPORAL FROM
FLORIDA, REMAINS REMAINS IN A MN
PRISON CHARGED WITH GUN
POSSESSION.
THE CHARGE IS TOTALLY BOGUS.
LAST SUMMER HE REGISTERED AN
ANTIQUE SHOTGUN, HANDED DOWN TO
HIM FROM HIS GREAT GRANDFATHER
WITH AMERICAN CUSTOMS OFFICIALS
IN BROWNSVILLE, TEXAS.
HE WAS THEN TOLD BY THE AMERICAN
AGENTS TO TAKE THE PAPERWORK
ACROSS THE BORDER TO MEXICAN
OFFICIALS AND HE WOULD BE FINE
TO TRAVEL ON TO COSTA RICA FOR A
HUNTING TRIP.
WHEN HE DID CHECK IN WITH THE
MEXICANS IN MATAMOROS, HE WAS
PROMPTLY ARRESTED AND CHARGED
WITH CARRYING A DEADLY WEAPON.
THAT WAS LAST AUGUST.
DESPITE MANY ATTEMPTS BY THE
U.S. GOVERNMENT TO GET HIM
RELEASED, MEXICO WILL NOT DO IT.
SO HE SITS IN A FILTHY PRISON
TEN DAYS BEFORE CHRISTMAS.
THAT'S SIMPLY UNACCEPTABLE.
EVERYBODY KNOWS CORPORAL HAMMER
DID NOTHING WRONG.
SO WHY DOESN'T MEXICO JUST
RELEASE HIM IN THE NAME OF
GOODWILL?
FOR YEARS TALKING POINTS HAS
BEEN TELLING YOU THAT MEXICO
DOES NOT ACT LIKE A FRIEND TO
THE USA.
I'VE STOPPED GOING TO THE
COUNTRY 'CAUSE THEY DO NOT -- I
DO NOT BELIEVE THEY'RE LOOKING
OUT FOR US.
THE JON HAMMER CASE PROVES THIS.
MEXICO'S NEW PRESIDENT SHOULD
RELEASE HAMMER IMMEDIATELY.
RIGHT NOW.
WE UNDERSTAND HIGH LEVEL
NEGOTIATIONS ARE TAKING PLACE
AND THERE IS SOME OPTIMISM THE
CORPORAL WILL SOON BE FREE.
BUT WHY IS IT TAKING SO LONG?
AND HOW DID IT EVER HAPPEN IN
THE FIRST PLACE?
WE WILL STAY ON THE STORY.
THAT'S A MEMO.
NOR FOR REACTION, JOINING US
FROM WASHINGTON, CONGRESSWOMAN
WHO IS DEEPLY INVOLVED IN THE
CASE.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND THIS.
I REALLY DON'T UNDERSTAND HOW
YOU CAN HAVE SOMEBODY IN JAIL
FOR FOUR MONTHS WHO DIDN'T DO
ANYTHING AND EVERYBODY IS
INVOLVED, THE STATE DEPARTMENT,
I ASSUME THE PRESIDENT KNOWS
ABOUT THIS.
SO TRY TO TELL ME WHAT'S GOING
ON.
>> WELL, WE ARE OUTRAGED AS
WELL, BILL.
IN FACT, IT IS SO
INCOMPREHENSIBLE THAT WHEN THE
MOTHER FIRST CAME TO US WITH THE
CASE, WE SAID, OH, SOMETHING
MUST BE WRONG HERE.
SOMETIMES CONSTITUENTS STRETCH
THE TRUTH A LITTLE BIT.
THIS CANNOT BE HAPPENING.
>> Bill: BUT IT IS.
>> THE MORE WE INVESTIGATED,
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE FOUND OUT ABSOLUTELY,
EVERYTHING THAT SHE WAS SAYING
IS ABSOLUTELY CORRECT.
AND, IN FACT, IN MY CONVERSATION
JUST TWO DAYS AGO WITH THE
MEXICAN AMBASSADOR, HE TOLD ME
THAT RIGHT NOW JON HAMMER IS
CHAINED TO HIS BED.
WHY?
BECAUSE THEY HAD TO MOVE HIM
FROM THE GENERAL POPULATION OF
THOSE CRIMINALS INTO AN AREA
THAT IS LESS SECURE.
AND IN THAT AREA THAT IS LESS
SECURE, IT IS SO UNSECURE THAT
THEY FEAR THAT HE WILL ESCAPE
AND IN ORDER TO OVERCOME THAT
FEAR, THEY HAVE CHAINED HIM TO
HIS BED.
>> Bill: DOES THE MEXICAN --
WHEN YOU TALKED TO THE MEXICAN
AMBASSADOR, DOES HE JUSTIFY
THIS?
I MEAN, HE DOESN'T HAVE THE
POWER TO RELEASE HIM.
I GUESS THE MEXICAN ATTORNEY
GENERAL WOULD DO THIS.
BUT DOES HE JUSTIFY THIS TRAVIS
SEE?
>> I DON'T WANT TO TALK ABOUT
CONVERSATIONS THAT I'VE HAD WITH
THIS OFFICIAL OR THE OTHER
OFFICIAL.
I CAN TELL YOU THIS, BILL, THE
MEXICAN GOVERNMENT IS PROBABLY
EVEN GOING TO BE POWERLESS
BECAUSE THEY BELIEVE THAT
THEY'RE UNDER SIEGE BY THESE
DRUG LORDS AND THEY HAVE CREED
CONTROL TO THESE GANGSTERS.
SO THE FOLKS ADMINISTERING THIS
TERRIBLE PRISON IS NOT THE
MEXICAN GOVERNMENT, BUT THESE
DRUG LORDS.
>> Bill: ARE YOU TELLING ME,
CONGRESSWOMAN, THE PRESIDENT OF
MEXICO DOES NOT HAVE ENOUGH
POWER TO RELEASE HAD AMERICAN
FROM THAT FILTHY PRISON IN
MATAMOROS?
IS THAT WHAT YOU'RE TELLING ME?
>> I BELIEVE HE DOESN'T HAVE THE
GUTS O DO IT.
DOES HE HAVE THE AUTHORITY TO DO
IT?
YES.
>> Bill: OF COURSE HE DOES.
>> THIS IS A CASE THAT WILL PUT
HIM TO THE TEST.
THIS IS A COUNTRY WHOSE LEADERS,
LEADER AFTER LEADER, THEY LOVE
TO LECTURE THE UNITED STATES
ABOUT HOW BADLY WE SUPPOSEDLY
TREAT ILLEGAL IMMIGRANTS.
HOGWASH.
HERE IS ANOTHER CASE, BECAUSE IT
IS NOT AN ISOLATED CASE -- OF AN
AMERICAN UNJUSTIFIABLY
IMPRISONED.
SO WE CALL ON THIS PRESIDENT TO
DO HIS DUTY AND RELEASE THIS --
>> Bill: I WANT OUR PRESIDENT TO
DO SOMETHING, TOO.
I WANT BARAK OBAMA TO SPEAK OUT
ABOUT THIS.
HE HAS REMAINED SILENT.
SO HAS SECRETARY OF STATE
CLINTON.
I UNDERSTAND THIS MUCH AND I
THINK YOU HINTED AT IT.
WE DON'T WANT TO MUCK UP ANY
NEGOTIATIONS THAT MIGHT BE
FRUITFUL BY ATTACKING ANYBODY
AND CALLING ANYBODY OUT MAKING
ANY THREATS.
THAT INCLUDES PRESIDENT OBAMA
AND SECRETARY OF STATE CLINTON.
WE'RE GOING TO ASSUME, YOU AND
TELL ME IF I'M WRONG, THAT THE
AMERICAN GOVERNMENT IS DOING
WHAT THEY SHOULD.
I'M SOAPING THEY ARE DOING WHAT
THEY SHOULD DO.
IS THAT RIGHT?
>> I DON'T GET THAT FEELING YET,
BILL.
MAYBE I'LL GET THAT FEELING --
>> Bill: SO YOU WANT MORE
PRESSURE PUT ON BY SECRETARY
CLINTON AND PRESIDENT OBAMA?
DO YOU WANT MORE PRESSURE?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
THAT'S WHY I'VE REACHED OUT TO
MY CONGRESSIONAL COLLEAGUES,
OVER 50 OF THEM HAVE SIGNED A
BIPARTISAN LETTER TO HILLARY
CLINTON AND JANET NAPOLITANO,
THE HEAD OF HOMELAND SECURITY,
CALLING FOR THEIR ADVOCACY FOR
JON HAMMER --
>> Bill: THEY NEED TO GET OUT IN
FRONT OF THIS!
THE NEWS MEDIA, "THE FACTOR" AND
YOU AND SENATOR NELSON, ALTHOUGH
HE DIDN'T MAKE HIMSELF AVAILABLE
THIS EVENING AND HE SHOULD HAVE,
YOU GUYS HAVE BEEN OUT IN FRONT.
LOOK, WE'LL GIVE IT THE WEEKEND.
WE'LL COME BACK MONDAY.
WE'LL SEE WHERE WE ARE.
WE'LL KEEP IN CONTACT WITH YOU,
CONGRESSWOMAN.
WE GOT TO GET THIS GUY OUT
BEFORE CHRISTMAS.
>> YOU ARE HIS LIFE POLICY.
I BELIEVE THAT --
>> Bill: WE'LL GET HIM OUT
BECAUSE NO AMERICAN IN -- WE'RE
GOING TO CALL FOR ABSOLUTE
BOYCOTT OF TRAVEL TO MEXICO IF
HE'S NOT OUT.
SIMPLE AS THAT.
>> THANK YOU FOR SAVING HIS
LIFE.
WE GOT THE WHOLE COMMUNITY
PRAYING FOR HIM.
>> Bill: WE'RE GOING TO WORK
TOGETHER AND GET IT DONE.
ALL RIGHT.
THANKS VERY MUCH.
>> THANK YOU, BILL.
>> Bill: IN A MOMENT, WE'LL
RECAP THAT HORRENDOUS MASS
MURDER IN CONNECTICUT.
HORRIBLE STORY.
THAT'S NEXT
>> Bill: BACK OF THE BOOK
SEGMENT, LET'S GO BACK TO
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
FOX NEWS ANCHOR BILL HEMMER IS
STANDING BY WITH AN UPDATE.
ALL RIGHT, HEMMER.
WE'RE STARTING TO NOW LEARN A
LITTLE BIT ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
INSIDE BY THE SCENE THAT THE
POLICE DESCRIBING.
TELL US ABOUT THAT.
>> IT IS A SCENE THAT CAN ONLY
BE DESCRIBED AS GRISLY AND A
SCENE THAT EVEN HARDENED POLICE
OFFICERS WORKING THE STATE FOR
DECADES HAVE NEVER SEEN BEFORE
IN THEIR LIVES.
BILL, WE BELIEVE ALL THE BODIES
ARE STILL INSIDE THAT SMALL
LITTLE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL DOWN
THE HILL FROM WHERE WE ARE AND
THEY WILL NOT BE MOVED TONIGHT
OR EVEN POSSIBLY TOMORROW OR
EVEN INTO SUNDAY.
THIS IS A GRISLY CRIME SCENE AND
THE POLICE ARE BEING VERY
PARTICULAR ABOUT MAKING SURE
THAT THEY ARE CAREFUL ABOUT THIS
EVIDENCE.
THIS IS A SCHOOL, BILL.
IT'S A TINY PLACE.
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRATE.
AND YOU COME UP HERE TO THIS
TOWN AND YOU THINK THIS IS THE
KIND OF COMMUNITY WITH YOU WANT
TO SEND YOUR KIDS TO SCHOOL.
YOU GO DOWN THIS HILL THROUGH
THE FOREST AND THE SCHOOL
EMERGES THERE, BILL.
THERE IS A SHORT LITTLE DRIVEWAY
RUNS ABOUT 75 YARDS LEADING UP
TO THE PARKING LOT OF THE
SCHOOL.
YOU WALK IN THERE AND YOU THINK,
WHAT IN THE WORLD COULD POSSIBLY
GO WRONG HERE?
AND TODAY EVERYTHING WENT WRONG.
OVERNIGHT TONIGHT, THESE POLICE
OFFICERS AND THESE INVESTIGATORS
ARE WORKING THIS CRIME SCENE TO
MAKE SURE THEY GET POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATION, SOMETHING THAT
WE EXPECT AT 8:00 A.M. TOMORROW
EASTERN TIME TO BE ANNOUNCED TO
THE REST OF THE COUNTRY.
>> Bill: OKAY.
WE HAVE AN IDENTIFICATION, THE
PRINCIPAL WHO WAS SHOT DEAD BY
THIS LANZA.
TELL US ABOUT HER.
>> I DON'T WANT TO GIVE OUT HER
NAME OUT OF RESPECT TO THE
COMMUNITY HERE BECAUSE POLICE
HAVE NOT GIVEN OUT HER NAME YET.
SHE'S 47 YEARS OLD.
SHE'S BEEN THE PRINCIPAL FOR TWO
YEARS, GOING BACK TO 2010.
WHICH BY THE WAY, WAS THE LAST
YEAR A SERIOUS CRIME WAS EVEN
REPORTED IN THE TOWN OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
SHE HAS FIVE KIDS.
TWO DAUGHTERS AND THREE
STEPDAUGHTERS, ALONG WITH HER
HUSBAND WHOSE FIRST NAME IS
GEORGE AND HE, TOO, IS A TEACHER
IN THIS SCHOOL DISTRICT.
HERE IS THE SAD AWFUL THING
ABOUT THIS, BILL.
WE'RE JUST GETTING INTO THE
HORROR OF WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
EVERY HOUR, THESE LAYERS PEEL
AWAY.
WE'RE GOING TO MEET THESE
VICTIMS IN A VERY INTIMATE WAY
OVERT COMING DAYS AS WE MOVE
THROUGH THE FUNERALS AND IT'S
ONLY GOING TO MAKE US MORE AND
MORE SAD AS WE WORK THROUGH IT
BECAUSE THESE LIVES HAVE BEEN
LOST AND WHEN WE LEARN ABOUT
PEOPLE LIKE IT WOMAN WHO WAS A
MOTHER OF FIVE AND BASED ON THE
POLICE ACCOUNTS WE HAVE, THE
GUNMAN WALKED IN THE PRINCIPAL'S
OFFICE FIRST AND COUNTED AT
LEAST FOUR ADULTS, ALL OF WHICH
WE BELIEVE, ALL OF WHOM WE
BELIEVE WERE WOMEN, INCLUDING
THE PRINCIPAL, AND SHOT THEM
DEAD ON SITE AT THAT MOMENT.
>> Bill: IT'S HARD TO COMPREHEND
ANY OF THIS, OF COURSE.
BUT I THINK PEOPLE HAVE TO
UNDERSTAND THAT EVEN THE
SURVIVORS AND THERE WERE OVER
600 KIDS IN THE SCHOOL.
I MEAN, IT'S A SMALL SCHOOL, BUT
THERE ARE A LOFT KIDS THERE.
ALL OF THEM ARE GOING TO BE
AFFECTED FOR THE REST OF THEIR
LIVES.
YOU DON'T KNOW -- YOU DON'T KNOW
HOW PERSONALITIES ABSORB THAT.
SO NOT ONLY ARE THE DEAD AND
GRIEVING FAMILIES WITH THEIR
PRIORITY NUMBER ONE, BUT ALL OF
THE OTHER CHILDREN, WE JUST
TALKED TO ONE EARLIER IN THE
PROGRAM, WHO LOOKED -- I DON'T
KNOW WHETHER YOU SAW THAT, BUT
SHE LOOKED LIKE, YOU KNOW, I'M
EIGHT YEARS OLD AND WHAT AM I
DEALING WITH HERE?
NEVER GOES AWAY.
IT NEVER GOES AWAY.
SO THE COMMUNITY IS GOING TO
HAVE TO PROVIDE SERVICES FOR
THOSE PEOPLE AND AS YOU SAID,
IT'S GOING TO UNFOLD AND NOW WE
HAVE A WOMAN WITH FIVE CHILDREN
AND YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE A LOT
OF THOSE STORIES.
>> YEAH.
ONE THING TO ADD ON THAT, I MET
IN A YOUNG GIRL BEFORE SHE
TALKED TO YOU, SOPHIA.
SHE WAS SO CHARMING.
SHE HAD A HUGE SMILE ON HER
FACE.
I MEAN, YOU LOOK IN HER PARENTS'
EYES AND Y THE TEARS
IN THEIR EYES AND THEY TRY AND
FIGHT IT BACK.
THEY HAVE THEIR DAUGHTER FOR
CHRISTMAS AND SO MANY OTHERS DO
NOT.
AND I SPOKE WITH A WOMAN EARLIER
TODAY, SHE HAS A DAUGHTER NAMED
ALEXIS.
SHE WAS A THIRD GRADER HERE,
SHE'S OKAY, TOO.
SHE SAID THROUGHOUT THE DAY,
THEY'VE BEEN TALKING, SHE'S BEEN
ASKING HER QUESTIONS.
THEN FINALLY HER DAUGHTER, FROM
THE THIRD GRADE, AGE EIGHT,
SAID, MOM, ARE YOU GOING TO BE
OKAY?
YOUR POINT IS WELL TAKEN ABOUT
HOW THEY ABSORB THIS AND HOW
THEY TRY AND INTERPRET IT AND
UNDERSTAND IT.
AND THEY, JUST LIKE IT WHOLE
TOWN, ARE NOW LEFT TO LIVE WITH
THIS FOR THE REST OF THEIR
LIVES, BILL.
>> Bill: THE ONLY ADVICE I COULD
GIVE TO ANYBODY THREW IS BE
STRONG.
PARENTS HAVE TO BE STRONG FOR
THEIR CHILDREN AND THEY HAVE TO
BE VERY WELL AWARE THAT THIS
THING IS GOING TO GO ON FOR A
LONG, LONG TIME.
ALL RIGHT.
GOOD JOB.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
AS ALWAYS, WE REALLY APPRECIATE
IT.
BILL WILL BE ON THROUGHOUT THE
EVENING.
FACTOR FACTOR TIP OF THE DAY.
SOME ADVICE TO AVOID BEING
CONNED THIS CHRISTMAS.
WE'LL HAVE THAT FOR YOU IN 60
SECONDS
>>> THE TIP OF THE DAY, DON'T
BE CONNED.
WE HAVE SOME GOOD NUSE, THANK
GOD.
BEST CHRISTMAS PROMOTION FOR
THE WEEKEND AND MONDAY IS
OVER.
FACT WORD BOOK.
IT IS A LOT OF FUN AND EDUCATE
THE KIDS.
IF YOU BUY THE BEST SELLING
BOOKS, YOU GET FACT WORD BOOK.
FREAVE CHARGE ONLY UNTIL
MONDAY AND SPILL BILL
O'REILLY.COMAND A BUMPER
STICKER FREE OF CHARGE.
THE FACTOR WANTS TO MAKE YOUR
CHRISTMAS BETTER.
YOUR TALKING POINTS ON
CHRISTMAS AND TRADITION
BROUGHT A TEAR TO MY EYE.
I AM PROUD TO CALL YOU MY
FRIENDINE THOUGH I DON'T KNOW
YOU.
>>> BEST TALKING POINTS EVER.
TOO BAD SOME DON'T SEE THE
TRUTH.
>>> MR. BILL, YOUR TALK POINTS
ARE FLAWED.
SAME CONCEPT AND BOTH DR. KING
SPOKE AND ENVOKING.
AND JESUS WAS A JEW.
AND THEY WERE HONORED BECAUSE
OF WHAT THEY DID FOR MANKIND.
I CAN'T MAKE IT CLEARER THAN
THAT, SHERRY.
>>> STANFORD, CONNECTICUT.
YOU REMINDED ME OF THE ABBOTT
AND COSTELO ROUTINE.
YOU WERE ABBOTT.
LANA COONY.
I SAY BECKLE WOULD BE MORE FUN
AT A PARTY THAN YOU AT A PARTY
O'REILLY.
BECKLE IS IN HIS PAJAMAS BY
NINE.
I WILL NOT GO JOHN HAMMER IS
RELEASED FROM PRISON.
CORPORAL HAMMER IS NOT
RELEASED, I AM CANCELLING MY
TRIP TO CANCUN.
I EXPECT THE MEXICO GOVERNMENT
TO DO THE RIGHT THING.
IF THEY DON'T ECONOMICS WILL
BE IF YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
BILL YOU AND IS DENNIS WERE
WONDERFUL IN SALT LAKE CITY.
I THINK YOU MEAN MILLER
THANKS.
>>> AND WE'LL SEE YOU ALL IN
PHOENIX, LA AND WASHINGTON
D.C. AND WESTBURY, LONG
ISLAND.
BILL, TOOK THE TIP OF THE DAY
AND VISITED MISSING MONEY.COM.
AND FOUND I WAS OWED $100.
AND PEEL OFF $20 FOR CHARITY
TOM.
>>> AND FINALLY TONIGHT THE
FACTOR TIP OF THE DAY.
MANY OF US GIVE TO CHARITY
OVER HANUKKAH AND CHRISTMAS
HOLIDAY SEASON IN GENERAL.
WE WANT TO BE SMART ABOUT IT,
DON'T WE.
GO TO CHARITY NAVIGATOR.ORG.
VERY HONEST WEB SITE.
IT RATES THE CHARITY SO YOU
CAN BE SURE THE MONEY IS USED
HONESTLY.
AND I USE CHARITY NAVIGATOR.
MOST OF THE CHARITIES THEY
GIVE TO I KNOW THE POEM.
I CAN GO TO THEIR HOUSE IF I
HAVE TO.
I HAVE SEEN IT AND SOMETIMES I
GIVE TO MONEY TO DOCTORS
WITHOUT BORDERS.
IT HAS THE LISTINGS ON CHARITY
NAVIGATOR.ORG.
SO YOU CAN KNOW.
WE ARE A GENEROUS PEOPLE IN
AMERICA.
MOST GENEROUS ON EARTH AND
SOMETIMES PEOPLE TAKE
ADVANTAGE OF THAT ASK RIP US
OFF.
YOU DON'T WANT THAT TO HAPPEN
TO YOU.
GO TO CHARITY NAVIGATOR.
CHECK OUT THE FOX NEWS FACTOR
WEB SITE.
WE'LL HAVE ALL OF THE LATEST
INFORMATION ON THE CONNECTICUT
SHOOTING.
HANNITY WILL DEAL WITH IT AND
GRETA WILL DO TWO HOURS AND WE
HAVE OUR GUYS AND GALS
STATIONED ALL AROUND.