THE WOMAN PLANS TO HELP A
CHILD IN NEED .
>> SINGER MIKE POZNER PENNED A
NEW SONG NAMED HEAVEN.
♪  AND I WILL UNDERSTAND WHY
YOU HAVE GONE.
HE HOPES THE SONG WILL HELP IN
A DIFFICULT TIME .
>> THAT IS IT FOR US.
FOX AND FRIENDS STARTS RIGHT
NOW.
>> Gretchen: GOOD
MORNING,ERVING.
TODAY IS TUESDAY, DECEMBER
18TH AND THIS IS IT A CAMERA
RUN.
HEY, EVERYONE.
I AM GRETCHEN CARLSON.
>> TWO MORE TINY VICTIMS LAID
TO REST TODAY AS FELLOW
STUDENTS TAKE ON THE DIFFICULT
TASK OF RETURNING TO CLASS .
WE ARE LIVE WITH THE LATEST
FOR YOU.
>> Steve: WE ARE ALSO GETTING
TO KNOW THE VICTIMS OF THE
HORRIBLE TRAGEDY LIKE THE HERO
TEACHER WHO STOPPED AT NOTHING
TO SAVE HER CHILDREN'S LIVES.
>> Brian: WE ARE GETTING A
FIRST LOOK AT THE MARINE
LOCKED NUP MEXICO.
HE'S CHAINED TO THE BED ALL
FOR HAVING A LEGAL GUN.
MEXICAN AUTHORITIES SAY IT IS
GOOD TREATMENT.
WE DISAGREE.
FOX AND FRIENDS STARTS RIGHT
NOW.
♪  FOX AND FRIENDS.
>> Gretchen: GOOD MORNING AND
THANKS FOR SHARING YOUR TIME
WITH US TODAY ON TUESDAY .
THIS IS THE SECOND DAY OF
GOODBYES IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT AS TWO MORE YOUNG
VICTIMS OF THE HORRIBLE
MASSACRE ARE LAID TO REST.
WE'LL GO OUT TO PETER DOOCY,
HE WILL TALK ABOUT JAMES, WHO
IS CALLED JAY.
HE WAS A NUMBERS GUY AND THE
OTHER IS JESSICA REKO WHO
LOVED EVERYTHING ABOUT HORSES
AND PLAYING WITH HER BROTHERS.
OTHER NEWTOWN SCHOOLS WILL
HEAD BACK TO SCHOOL.
AND WE'LL HEAR MORE ON WHAT
LED TO THE SHOOTING.
HI, PETER.
>> GRETCHEN, LAST NIGHT I WAS
WALKING AROUND AND THE STREETS
ARE PACKED WITH PEOPLE MILLING
ABOUT IN COMPLETE SILENCE.
THE ONLY NOISE YOU HEAR ARE
CARS AND TRUCKS PASSING BY .
YESTERDAY, SEVERAL OF THOSE
TRUCKS WERE MOVING TRUCKS
COMPLETE WITH THEIR OWN POLICE
ESCORT TAKING THE FURNITURE
FROM INSIDE OF SANDY HOOK OVER
TO MONO, RON MONROE TO CHALK
HILL MIDDLE SCHOOL WHICH IS
WHERE STUDENTS DISPLACED BY
THE AWFUL TRAGEDY WILL GO BACK
TO CLASS WHEN THE DISTRICT
DECIDES THAT THE TIME IS
RIGHT.
>> THE SANDY HOOK SCHOOL
FURNITURE IS GOING TO BE MOVE
OUT AND SO IT WILL BE AGE AND
HEIGHT AND WAIT APPROPRIATE.
BUT THE HEALING AND THE BACK
TO NORMAL SEE IS WORTH EVERY
EFFORT.
>> AUTHORITIES SAY THEY HAD NO
CONTACT WITH ADAM LANZA BEFORE
HIS MASSACRE ON FRIDAY AND ANY
KIND OF A CRIMINAL BACKGROUND
IS A MIST ROW TO AUTHORITIES
HERE WHO - MYSTERY TO
AUTHORITIES HERE TO WHAT MADE
HIM DO SUCH A HORRIBLE THING.
TWO ADULTS THAT ARE SURVIVING
THE MASSACRE ARE RECOVERING
FROM GUN SHOT WOUNDS TO THEIR
LOWER EXTREMITIES.
THE CONNECTICUT POLICE PROMISE
WE WILL GET THE DETAILS BUT IT
WILL TAKE A WHILE.
I KNOW, WE KNOW AS
INVESTIGATORS THAT THE PEOPLE
OF THE CONNECTICUT AND PEOPLE
IN THE TOWN OF NEWTOWN WANT TO
KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
WE ARE GOING TO DO THAT AND
PROVIDE THEM WITH INFORMATION
AND PAINT THEM A CLEAR PICTURE
BUT IT IS A SLOW PROCESS ROADS E
CLOSED FOR THE FUNERAL OF THE
YOUNG CHILDREN.
EVEN THOTE BEAUTIFUL NEW
ENGLAND TOWN IS NICELY
DECORATED FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
THERE ARE TWEN CHILDREN AND
SIX ADULTS THAT WILL NEVER
SPEND THE HOLIDAYS WITH THEIR
FAMILIES EVER AGAIN.
BACK TO YOU IN NEW YORK.
>> WE ARE TRYING TO LOOK AT
WHAT IS UNFOLDING AND TRYING
TO PUT TOGETHER ON THE DAY OF
THE ACTUL MASSACRE ON FRIDAY
AT 9:30.
THERE WILL BE A SECOND
SURVIVOR THAT WAS ABLE TO LIVE
THROUGH THE WOULD YOU KNOWS
THEY OBTAINED IN THE ATTACK
AND ONE FASCINATING STORY
ABOUT THE 27 YEAR OLD TEACHER
WHO LOST HER LIFE TRYING TO
SAVE HER CHILDREN.
>> YOU ARE TALKING ABOUT
VICTORIA SOTO TRYING TO GET
THEM IN THE CLOSEST.
THEY FREAKED OUT WHEN THEY
HEARD THE SHOOTING AND WENT
RUNNING AND SIX OF THEM WERE
SHOT.
THERE SHE IS RIGHT THERE.
SHE DIED.
TRYING TO SAVE THEM.
CLEARLY A HERO TEACHER.
HER COLLEGE ROOM MAN WENT TO
EASTERN CONNECTICUT STATE
UNIVERSITY AND ROOMMATES FOR
MOST OF THE COLLEGE CAREERS
AND SHY TALKED TO ONE OF OUR
AFFILIATES IN TEXAS DESCRIBING
A YOUNG WOMAN, VICTORIA SOTO
WHO LOVED TO TEACH WITH ALL OF
HER HEART.
>> SHE LOVED HER JOB AND SHE
LOVED THEM AND I WAS NOT
SURPRISED THAT SHE WOULD
PROTECT THEM AND GIVE THEIR
LIFE TO SAVE THEIRS.
I KNEW VICKI WOULD DO THAT.
THESE KIDS WERE HER LIFE .
>> SHOW HAD THEM IN THE
CLOSEST AND THEN SHE WAS
TRYING TO DISTRACT THE SHOOTER
BY SAYING THEY WENT TO THE GYM
NASIUM.
AND IN THE SINCE OF PANIC.
KIDS RAN OUT AND THEY LOST
THEIR LIVES ALONG WITH HER.
THIS IS IT THE VICTORIA SOTO
AS SHE IS GETTING HER REACTION
TO WHAT SHE IS FINDING OUT.
>> Brian: SHE IS NOT FINDING
OUT ABOUT HER SISTER.
>> Steve: BEGGING FOR
INFORMATION ABOUT HER SISTER.
OUTSIDE OF THE SCHOOL.
SHE SAID THAT PICTURE WILL
HAWN HER FOR THE REST OF THE
HER LIFE BECAUSE IT BROUGHT
HER BACK TO THE MOMENT AND IT
WILL BE AN ICONIC PHOTO.
TELL GET WORSE FOR HER.
WHAT ABOUT THE REST OF THE
SOTO'S CLASS THEY RAN OUT OF
THE BUILD THEYENED UP ON THE
FRONT LAWN OF PSYCHICOLOGIST
OF JEAN ROSEN.
>> Steve: HE HAD BEEN IN A
DINER AND THERE IS A PICTURE
OF HIM AFTER HE REALIZED WHAT
HAPPENED.
AND HE FOUND IN THE END OF HIS
DRIVEWAY SIX OF THEM SITTING
IN A CIRCLE.
WE CAN'T GO BACK TO SCHOOL .
MRS. SOTO IS DEAD.
HE DIDN'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
THEY WERE TERRIFIED.
HE DIDN'T UNDERSTAND.
AND HE WAS PUTTING IT TOGETHER
HE TOCK THEM TO HIS HOUSE AND
HAD THEM, A BUS DRIVER SHOWED
UP AND SHE HAD THE PHONE
NUMBERS TO THE CHILDREN'S
PARENTS AND THEY CALLED THE
PARENTS TO LET THEM KNOW THEY
WERE OKAY .
HE GAVE THEM JUICE AND STUFFED
ANIMALS AND HE WAS THERE FOR
THEM.
>> Gretchen: ANOTHER MOTHER
CAME TO HIS DOOR AND SAID I
HEARD YOU HAD SOME OF THE
SURVERIFYING CHILDREN HERE AT
THE HOME, DID YOU HAVE MY
CHILD AND HE SAID HE LATER
READ THAT THAT CHOILED HAD
DIED.
>> Brian: SO MUCH OF THAT
STORY THESE KIDS ARE ABLE TO
ABSORB.
THE BIG GUN AND LITTLE GUN .
THAT MEANS THEY DIDN'T STAY IN
THE CLOSEST.
THEY RAN OUT PROBABLY ALL AT
THE SAME TIME MAYBE NOT IN THE
SAME SECTION.
SIX PANICKED RAN OUT AND
OTHERS STAYED.
IT SEEMS BY WHAT THE KIDS ARE
SAYING.
THEY RAN OUT ASK THEY AVOIDED
BEING SHOT.
AND SOME OF THE FAMILIES ARE
DEALING WITH THIS IN WAYS.
THE QUESTION IS WHETHER OR NOT
YOU TELL THEM ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED.
A LOT OF THE KIDS HAVE NOT
BEEN TOLD WHAT HAPPENED.
AND A LOT OF PARENTS ARE NOT
GOING TO LET THE KIDS GO TO
SCHOOL FOR A WHILE.
AND IT WILL BE INTERESTING TO
SEE HOW MANY KIDS DO GO THAT
FAR.
FOX NEWS CONFIRMED THAT THE
PRESIDENT OF IRAQ IS IN A COMA
AFTER SUFFERING A STROKE.
THEY ARE NOT DECOIDED WHETHER
HE WILL BE FLOWN TO ANOTHER
COUNTRY FOR TREATMENT.
HE HAD SIGNS OF FATIGUE.
DOW JONES WILL TRY TO SELL THE
GOP ON THE LATEST PLAN TO
AVOID GOING OFF THE FISCAL
CLIFF .
SOURS SAY IT INCLUDES ONE
TRILLION IN SPENDING CUTS AND
ONE TRILLION IN REVENUE ALSO
THE CHANCE THAT THE DEBT
CEILING WOULD BE INCROSED ONE
YEAR AND STILL YET TO BE
DETERMINED IF TAX RATES WILL
GO UP FOR SOME AMERICANS.
THE PRESIDENT IS OFFERING A
TAX RATE HIKE ON THOSE MAKES
MORE THAN $400,000 A YEAR .
THAT IS A CHANGE FROM $250,000
OR AND SOME REPUBLICANS ARE
CONCERNED THAT PARTY LEADERS
HAVE MADE TOO MANY
CONCESSIONS.
KEY LAW MAKERS ARE DETAILED ON
THE REPORT ON THE BENGHAZI
LIBYA TERROR ATAX.
AND ON THURSDAY TWO OF
SECRETARY OF STATE HOL AIDS
WILL TESTIFY ABOUT THE ACT IN
FRONT OF CONGRESS.
SHE FELL AND SUFFERED A
CONCUSSION AND WILL NOT BE
ABLE TO BE THERE.
FORMER AMBASSADOR TO THE
UNITED NATIONS DOESN'T BELIEVE
IT ADDS UP.
>> EVERY FOREIGN MINISTRY
KNOWS THE PHRASE I WILL ABOUT
TO USE.
WHEN YOU DON'T WANT TO GO TO A
MEETING OR CONFERENCE EVENT
YOU HAVE A DIPLOMATIC ILLNESS
AND THIS IS ONE TO BEAT THE
BAND.
I CERTAINLY HOPE IT IS NOTHING
SERIOUS AND THIS WAS REVEAL
WOULD IN A WAY THAT WAS NOT
TRANSPARENT AND I THINK THERE
IS AN OBLIGATION HERE.
>> DOCTORS SAY IT MAY TAKE
SEVERAL WEEKS BEFORE
MRS. CLINTON CAN GET BACK TO
WORK.
>> HE REPRESENTS HAWAII FROM
THE TIME IT BICAME A STATE IN
1951.
AND IN 1945 IN WORLD WAR II,
HE WAS LOBBYING HAND GRENADES
TO THE ENEMY AND LOST HIS ROIT
ARM.
HE WAS FRIENDS WITH A FELLOW
AMERICAN SOLDIER NAMED BOB
DOLE AND THEY WENT TOGETHER TO
CHAMPION FOR VETERAN'S RIGHTS
.
THE SENATOR DIED FROM
RESPIRATORY COMPLICATIONS AND
HE WAS 88 YEARS OLD AND HIS
LAST WORD WAS ALOHA.
>> Steve: WE TOLD YOU THE
STORY OVER THE LAST COUPLE OF
WEEKS BY THE MARINE BY THE
NAME OF JOHN HAMMER.
HE WAS GOING HUNTING TO COSTA
RICKA AND WHEN HE WAS IN
MATAMORAS MEXICO.
HE DECLARED I HAVE THIS GUN
AND THEY SAY IT IS NOT A
PROPER SIZE.
THEY THREW HIM IN JAIL.
HE DID NOT HAVE THE PROPER
PERMITS.
BUT WHAT IS INTERESTING ABOUT
THAT ISOLATION CELL.
IT IS A STORAGE CLOSEST.
>> Gretchen: HE'S CHAINED TO
THE BED.
AND WE INTERVIEWED HIS MOTHER
AND HE'S BEEN CHAINED THEIR
SINCE AUGUST.
HE GOT THE GUN FROM HIS GREAT
GRAND FATHER HE REGISTERED IT
BEFORE HE CROSSED THE BORDER
AND HE WAS TOLD IT IS OKAY.
IS HE HELD ILLEGALLY ON FALSE
CHARGES.
HED REPRESENTATIVES IN STATE
OF FLORIDA.
RUBIO AND OTHERS TO HELP HIM.
SO FAR, THE STATE DEPARTMENT
DOES NOT APPEAR THEY ARE
INVOLVED AS SOME BELIEVE THEY
SHOULD .
>> Brian: HERE'S THE BIG
THING.
IT TURNS OUT THE GUN IS LEGAL
.
HE SHOULDN'T BE IN JAIL LET
ALONE TREATED LIKE THIS AS A
AMERICAN MARINE.
THIS IS OUTRAGEOUS AND WE'LL
FOLLOW THE STORY.
>> Steve: IT IS IT A TRUMPED
UP GUN CHARGE.
HIS HOT GUN WAS -- I HOPE HE'S
WATCHING.
MR. PRESIDENT, THIS IS WHAT
YOUR COUNTRY IS DOING TO THIS
PROUD MARINE.
YOU CRACK DOWN WITH A GUN THAT
IS 25 OR LESS.
AND THIS IS 24.
IT IS ONE INCH LOWER THAN THE
STANDARD IT IS TRUMPED UP.
>> Gretchen: DRUG CARTELS RUN
THE PRISONS.
HIS MOM IS COMING ON OUR SHOW
IN THE 8:00 HOUR.
THERE IS A HUGE DEBATE IN OUR
COUNTRY.
>> Brian: JOHN BOEHNER AGREED
TO TAX HIKES, BUT NOW THE
PRESIDENT HAS ANOTHER REQUEST.
WILL THE REPUBLICANS BUY IT.
MYA LOVE IS ON DECK AND RIGHT
THROUGH THE DOOR.
BEGIN.
TOMATO,
OBVIOUSLY.
HAHA. THERE'S MORE
THAN THAT THOUGH,
THERE'S A KICK TO IT.
WAHLALALALALLALA!
SMOOTH, BUT CRISP.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE DRINKING
A FOOD THAT'S A DRINK,
OR A DRINK THAT'S A FOOD,
WOOOOOH!
[ Male Announcer ] TASTE IT
AND DESCRIBE THE INDESCRIBABLE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
AND WITH MY BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CREDIT CARD,
I LOVE 'EM EVEN MORE.
I EARN 1% CASH BACK EVERYWHERE,
EVERTIME.
2% ON GROCERIES.
3% ON GAS.
AUTOMATICALLY.
NO HOOPS TO JUMP THROUGH.
THAT'S 1% BACK ON...
[ toy robot sounds ]
2% ON PUMPN PIE.
AND APPLE.
3% BACK ON 4 TRIPS
TO THE AIRPORT.
IT'S AS EASY AS..
-[ man ] 1...
-[ woman ] 2...
[ woman ] 3.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CARD.
APPLY ONLINE OR AT
A BANK OF AMERICA NEAR YOU.
>> Steve: YOU ARE LOOKING LIVE
AT WASHINGTON D.C. IN THE
CAPITOL, BELIEVE IT OR NOT LAW
MAKERS HOPING TO AVOID THE
FISCAL CLIFF ARE MAKING
PROGRESS.
AIDES SAID THEY WERE CLOSER TO
CUTTING A DEAL.
BUT ONE THING THAT WILL NOT
CLICK IS TAX HIKES.
HOW MUCH WOULD THEY BE AND WHO
WILL WOULD HAVE TO PAY THEM
WHEN IT COME TO REVENUE.
JOINING US IS SARADOGA
SPRINGS, UTAH MAYOR MYA LOVE.
HE WANTED TAX INCREASES AND
WOULD NOW SETTLE FOR 1.2
TRILLION AND IMPACT $400,000
OR MORE.
AND SOUNDS LIKE HE SQUISHED A
BIT ON IT AND WHAT DO YOU
THINK ABOUT THE SUPPOSED DEAL?
>> IT IS NOT MUCH MOVEMENT
FROM THE PRESIDENT'S SIDE.
IN IF YOU ARE GOING FOR
$250,000 TO $400,000 THAT IS
NOT MUCH.
YOUNG CAME OUT WITH A REPORT
SAYING IF YOU TAX THE TOP TWO
BRACKETS THAT WILL COST YOU
700,000 JOBS.
THESE ARE JANITORS GOING IN
AND HAVING THEIR MANAGER SAY I
AM SORRY WECAN'T AFFORD YOU
ANY LONGER AND THESE PEOPLE
ARE WORKING PAY CHECK TO PAY
CHECK.
THEY NEED MON TOW FEED THEIR
FAMILY.
>> Gretchen: -
>> Steve: THE PRESIDENT WANTED
A TWO YEAR DEBT LIMIT.
AND THAT WAS THE REPUBLICANS
LEVERAGE.
IT SEEMS LIKE THE REPUBLICANS
ARE GETTING THE SHORT END OF
THE STICK.
>> Steve: IT IS THE ONLY
LEVERAGE THEY HAD TO NEGOTIATE
A DEAL AND TO GIVE THAT UP FOR
TWO YEARS.
WHAT WILL HAPPEN NEXT YIRE?
THEY HAVE BEGIN UP EVERY
LEVERAGE THEY HAVE.
THE PRESIDENT HOLDS ALL OF THE
CARDS HERE AND THE
ADMINISTRATION HOLDS THE CARD
GIVE THAT UP FOR TWO YEARS IS
RIDICULOUS.
>> Steve: YOU LISTEN TO
CHARLES KRAUTHAMMER MADE A
GREAT POINT.
THE REPUBLICANS STILL HOLD THE
HOUSE AND IT IS STILL DIVIDED
GOVERNMENT IF THE PRESIDENT
WAS TO SAIL OFF THE FISCAL
CLIFF, THAT WOULD DAMAGE HIS
LEGACY AND THE PRESIDENT
DOESN'T WANT THAT.
THAT WOULD BE TIME FOR LET'S
MAKE A DEAL.
>> I THINK WE BACKED OURSELVES
IN UATION WHERE IT IS
LOSE-LOSE FOR THE REPUBLICANS
AND THE AMERICAN PEOPLE.
WE ARE TRYING TO FORM
POLITICAL POLICY WITHOUT
POLITICAL OPINION.
WE HAVE TO GET THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE BEHIND US.
WE ARE FIGHTING THE SAME
BATTLES WITH AS THE 13TH.
AND INSTEAD OF OWNED BY A
PLANITATION OWNER WE ARE
ENSLAVED TO THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT.
>> Steve: IF THEY ARE CUTTING
TAXES A TRILLION AND CUT
SPENDING A TRILLION THAT IS A
WASH.
>> WE HAVE A SERIOUS SPENDING
PROBLEM.
WE AT OUR HOMES HAVE TO LIVE
WITHIN OUR MINES AND WE
WASHINGTON TO DO THE SAME
THING AND IT IS NOT HAPPENING.
>> Steve: THANK YOU FOR BEING
HERE.
STRAIGHT AHEAD NEARLY EVERY
MASS MURDERER HAS A HISTORY OF
MENTAL ILLNESS.
IS IT TIME TO ADDRESS THAT IN
OUR NATION?
COMING TO THE MOVIE THEATER
NEAR YOU.
BUBA, MAKING A MOVIE ABOUT
WILLIAM JEFFERSON CLINON.
BAKED IN A KETCHUP GLAZE
WITH SAVORY GRAVY
AND MASHED RUSSET POTATOES.
WHAT MAKES STOUFFER'S MEATLOAF
BEST OF ALL?
THAT MOMENT YOU ENJOY IT
AT HOME.
STOUFFER'S. LET'S FIX DINNER.
[ coughs ]
[ baby crying ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
ROBITUSSIN® LIQUID FORMULA
SOOTHES YOUR THROAT ON CONTACT
AND THE ACTIVE INGREDIENT
RELIEVES YOUR COUGH.
ROBITUSSIN®. DON'T SUFFER
THE COUGHEQUENCES™.
TO COME HOME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE...
SADLY, THEIR BROTHER'S
WHITE CHRISTMAS
JUST GOT "BLACKED OUT."
[ Brother ]
BUT IT'S THE FAMILY PARTY!
REALLY JINGLES YOUR BELLS,
DOESN'T IT?
MY GIFT TO YOU!
THE Capital One Venture Card!
FOR ANY FLIGHT, ANY TIME!
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE!
HOW ILLUMINATING.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
LET ME GUESS, AM
ON THE NAUGHTY LIST AGAIN?
HO HO HO!
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>> Brian: THE MAN ACCUSED OF
KILLING TWO POLICE OFFICERS IN
TOPEKA, KANSAS IS DEAD.
WHEN HE RAN OUT HE WAS
CARRYING A GUN.
HE WAS SHOT.
AUTHORIZED DOCUMENTARY OF
PRESIDENT CLINTONON.
THEY ARE KEEPING TIGHT LIPPED
ON WHETHER IT WILL INCLUDE
MONICA LEWINSKY.
HE'S LOOKING FORWARD TO
SHARING HIS PERSPECTIVE ON HIS
CAREERS AS PRESIDENT.
GRETCH.
THANK - ON >> Gretchen: THANK
YOU BRIKNOW.
THE GUNMAN ADAM LANZA MAY HAVE
HAD A FORM OF MENTAL ILLNESS.
THEY SUSPECTED OTHER
CONDITIONS LIKE VIRGINIA
TECH'S SUN HU CHO.
AND COLORADO'S JAMES HOLMES.
HOW CAN THE COUNSEL ROW TACKLE
THE QUESTION OF MENTAL HEALTH
IN DR. ABLO, THIS IS YOUR LINE
OF WORK.
I THINK A LOT OF PEOPLE DON'T
ENVY YOUR POSITION OF TRYING
TO CARE FOR PEOPLE WITH MENTAL
ILLNESS.
WHERE DO WE STAND IN REGARD TO
HELPING TAKE CARE OF PEOPLE
WITH MENTAL ILLNESS.
NIT IS A PRIVILEGE TO TAKE
CARE OF THEM.
WHERE WE STAND RIGHT NOW IN
TERPS OF MENTAL ILLNESS.
WE HAVE DISASSEMBLED THE
MENTAL HEALTH CARE SYSTEM SO
IT EXIST.
SOMEONE WHO IS AT RISK FOR
VIOLENCE AND HAS A HISTORY OF
THE VIOLENCE IS LIKE LOW TO BE
TREATED BY A SOCIAL WORKER AN
HOUR A WEEK FOR COUNSELING AND
A NURSE CLINITITION TO GET
MEDICINE.
AND THERE ARE LITERALLY
THOUSANDS OF FAMILIES TRYING
TO COPE WITH THE FACT THAT
THEIR KIDS ARE
METROPOLITANALLY ILL AND THE
BEST THEY CAN DO WHEN THEY ARE
SICK, IS MAYBE STAY IN A
HOSPITAL FOR THREE OR FOUR
DAYS UNTIL THEY PROMISE NOT TO
KILL ANYONE THAT'S WHAT WE
ALLOWED TO HAPPEN.
NWE DON'T HAVE A AT PRESENT.
>> Gretchen: WHY ARE WE SEEING
MORE OF THE YOUNG BOYS
PACIFICLY DO THESE TYPES OF
THINGS?
WHAT DID THEY USED TO DO?
IF THEY HAD THIS MUCH RAGE,
WAS THE OLD WAY THAT
MANIFESTED ITSELF?
>> FIRST OF ALL.
THERE ARE NEW STRESSES
INCLUDING INTRUSION OF
TECHNOLOGY AND OTHERS THAT
DEHUMANIZES PEOPLE AND OUR
POPULATION MAY HAVE CHANGED .
WE HAVE REMOVED THE PSYCHIATRY
FROM THE MENTAL HEALTH CARE
SYSTEM AND THEY ARE NOT
TRAINED IN PSYCHOTHERAPY.
THEY ARE POEM WHO PRESCRIBE TO
SIX PATIENTS AN HOUR AND
SEEING EVERY NINE DAYS AND
WHY?
BECAUSE INSURANCE COMPANIES
PAY BETTER FOR THAT IT IS
PRESUMED AND FIREWORKS WHO
WANT THE REAL EXPERTIS OF A
PSYCHIATRIST AND HELP HAVE TO
PAY OUT OF THE POCKET.
RESIDENCY TRAINING PROGRAMS
DON'T PAY FOR THAT.
>> THERE IS IT A STIGMA IN OUR
SOCIETY ABOUT MENTAL ILLNESS.
AND STATES HAVE LAWS AND
REGARD TO MANDATING
MEDICATION.
CAN YOU EXPLAIN THAT TO ME?
>> THIS IS IT A BIG TOPIC AND
IT COULD BE FIXED.
NUMBER ONE.
THE STATE HOSPITAL SYSTEM
ABSORBED THE FOLKS WHO CONT BE
CARED FOR.
AND WE DECIMATED THAT SYSTEM.
AND IF YOU NEED MORE TIME YOU
CAN'T GET IT TOO MANY STATES,
THE VAST MAJORITY OF THE
STATES DON'T HAVE A RULE BY
WHICH THEY CAN GO TO COURT AND
SAY THIS YOUNG MAN NEEDS TO
TAKE THE MEDICINE.
THERE ARE VIOLENT ACTS IN THE
PAST AND HE'S UNRELIABLE
TAKING IT AND HE SHOULD TAKE
IF IN A OUTPATIENT ENVIRONMENT
AND HE SHOULD GO TO THE
HOSPITAL.
YOU CAN GO TO THE HOSPITAL
BECAUSE YOU ARE SO VIOLENT AND
ONCE YOU HIT THE STRITES THERE
IS NO MECHANISM TO ENFORCE
YOUR TREATMENT.
THAT HAS TO GO AWAY.
>> Gretchen: DR., THANK YOU
FOR BEING PART OF OUR TEAM.
COMING UP ON FOX AND FRIENDS.
GUNS USED IN UTAH USED
LEGALLY.
WHAT HISTORY SAY.
THINK YOU CAN MULTITASK.
THIS WOMAN IS DEDEFINING ALL
HANDS ON DECK.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY TO THE VOICE
JUDGE.
.
[ Dylan ] THIS IS ONE WAY
TO KEEP YOUR UNDERWEAR CLEAN.
THIS IS ANOTHER!
TA-DAA!
TRY CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG.
IT CLEANS SO WELL AND YOU CAN
USE UP TO FOUR TIMES LESS
THAN THE LEADING VALUE
BRAND.
OH! THERE IT IS.
THANKS SON.
HEY!
[ Female Announcer ]
CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG
HAS A DURACLEAN TEXTURE
THAT CAN HELP YOU GET CLEAN
WHILE STILL USING LESS.
AND IT'S FOUR TIMES STRONGER
VERSUS THE LEADING VALUE BRAND.
CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG HELPS KEEP
YOU AND YOUR UNDERWEAR CLEAN.
WE ALL GO. WHY NOT ENJOY THE GO
WITH CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG?
CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG HELPS KEEP
YOU AND YOUR UNDERWEAR CLEAN.
THERE'S THE SIGN TO THE BULLPEN.
HERE HE COMES.
YOU WOULDN'T WANT YOUR
DOCTOR DOING YOUR JOB,
THE PITCH!
WHOA!
SO WHY ARE YOU DOING HIS?
ONLY YOUR DOCTOR CAN DETERMINE
IF YOUR PERSISTENT HEARTBURN
IS ACTUALLY SOMETHING
MORE SERIOUS
LIKE ACID REFLUX DISEASE.
OVER TIME, STOMACH
ACID CAN DAMAGE
THE LINING OF YOUR ESOPHAGUS.
FOR MANY, PRESCRIPTION NEXIUM
NOT ONLY PROVIDES
24-HOUR HEARTBURN RELIEF,
BUT CAN ALSO HELP HEAL
ACID-RELATED EROSIONS IN
THE LINING OF YOUR ESOPHAGUS.
THERE IS RISK OF BONE FRACTURE
AND LOW MAGNESIUM LEVELS.
SIDE EFFECTS MAY INCLUDE
HEADACHE, ABDOMINAL
PAIN AND DIARRHEA.
CALL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY IF
YOU HAVE PERSISTENT DIARRHEA.
OTHER SERIOUS STOMACH
CONDITIONS MAY EXIST.
DON'T TAKE NEXIUM IF
YOU TAKE CLOPIDOGREL.
LET YOUR DOCTOR DO HIS JOB.
AND YOU DO YOURS.
ASK IF NEXIUM IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
IF YOU CAN'T AFFORD
YOUR MEDICATION,
ASTRAZENECA MAY BE ABLE TO HELP.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] CAMPBELL'S
GREEN BEAN CASSEROLE.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO
>> THERE IS ONE EMBARRASSING
MOMENT.
EVERYTHING IS GOING GREAT
UNTIL THEY LIT THE MENORAH AND
JOE BIDEN RAN IN AND BLEW OUT
THE CANDLES.
VERY EMBARRASSING.
>> Gretchen: THERE IS NOT MUCH
TO SAY AFTER THAT JOKE.
>> Brian: JIMMY KIMBLE.
AND JAY LENO AND DAVID
LETTERMAN AND YOUR FAVORITE.
>> Steve: VODKA GIRL .
>> Gretchen: DO SHOTS ON
THERE.
>> Brian: NO, I AM BEING
SARCASTIC.
I THINK IT IS IT EXCITING LATE
NIGHT TELEVISION.
>> Gretchen: YOU KNOW MORE
ABOUT LATE NIGHT THAN MOST.
>> Steve: HE IS UP.
>> Gretchen: I DON'T KNOW WHEN
HE SLEEPS.
>> Brian: I THINK JIMMY KIMBLE
GOING TO 11 TIME TIME 30 IS
SIGNIFICANT.
THEY HAD BEEN TRYING TO CANCEL
HIM.
MR. #1: WE PLAY THE FUNNY
STUFF EARLY .
WE HAVE NEWS LIKE WE DO AND
THESE ARE THE HEAD LINES.
THIS IS IT GIGANTIC NEWS.
FIRST FRECK FRECK SENATOR EVER
IN THE STATE OF CAROLINAMENT
REPUBLICAN TIM SCOTT.
THE GOVERNOR THE SOUTH
CAROLINA PICKED SCOTT.
>> ONLY IN THE COUNTRY CAN AN
INDIAN FEMALE BE GOVERNOR AND
FRECK FRECK BE SENATOR AND
EVERY CHILD NO MATTER WHAT
RACE OR GENDER CAN GROW UP TO
BE WHATEVER THEY WANT.
HE WILL BE THE FIRST FRECK
FRECK SENATOR THE SOUTH HAS
AFRICAN SENATOR THE SOUTH
CAROLINA HAS ON SEEN.
>> Brian: THE TREE CRASHED IN
THE ROOM.
>> COME DOWN STAIRS AND SAW
THE TREE HIT THE NEIGHBOR'S
HOUSE IT IS IT THE BABY'S
ROOM.
>> THERE WERE BROKEN TRUSSES
AND SHEETING HANGING DOWN.
I AM SURE IT WAS SCARY FOR
THES.
>> Brian: CAN CAME WITHIN A
COUPLE OF PHOT FROM THE CRIB.
THE BABY DIDN'T HAVE A SCRATCH
ON HIM.
HE WAS CHECKED OUT IN THE
HOSPITAL AS A PRECAUTION.
>> Gretchen: HE WILL BE HOME
FOR CHRISTMAS.
FORMER PRESIDENT BUSH WILL BE
RELEASED FROM THE HOSPITAL
WITHIN A WEEK.
HE IS TREATED FOR A BRONCHITUS
RELATED COUGH.
HE'S BEEN IN THE HOSPITAL
SINCE NOVEMBER 23RD.
>> Steve: THIS BRINGS
MULTITASKING TO A NEW LEVEL.
THIS CHINESE WOMAN CAN WRITE
WITH BOTH HANDS AT THE SAME
TIME AND WRITE IN BOTH LEARNS.
>> SHE WAS TRYING TO GET
EVERYTHING DONE.
I FEEL A SLACKER.
AMAZING.
ON THE WHITE BOARD.
>> Brian: SUDDENLY FEEL LIKE A
SLACKER.
JETS LONG SHOT PLAYOFF HOPES
ON THE LINE AGAINST THE
TENNESSEE TIITANCE.
IF I GET A LITTLE BIT I AM SO
FASTER THAN THE WHITE JERSEY.
I WASTED ENOUGH TIME.
HE SCORES A TOUCH TOUCH.
AND MARK SANCHEZ HAS A CHANCE
TO GO UP.
WRONG TEAM.
AND THEY HAD FOUR
INTERCEPTIONS AND GETS WORSE
FOR THE JETS AND IN THE SHOT
GUN.
AND BAD SNAP AND JETS LOSE
14-10.
FOR MORE ON THE JETS PLAYOFFS
HOPES EVAPERATING IS JOLE.
YOUR REACTION.
ONLY A THREE HOUR SHOW.
NUMBER 10 IS NUMBER ONE.
RED SKINS QUARTERBACK SETTING
A RECORD FOR JERSEY SALES MORE
PEOPLE BOUGHT RG3 JERSEYS THAN
ANY OTHER PLAYER.
SORRY, TIM TEBOW.
WORD IS HE MIGHT BE A
REPUBLICAN.
AND NEWTOWN SCHOOL SHOOTING.
THEY HELD A MOMENT OF SILENCE.
UCONN BEAT MARYLAND 84-50.
AND THEY CREATED A
SCHOLARSHIP.
BY THE WAY, UCONN COACH AND
HIS WIFE DONATING 80,000.
ONE OF THE BEST BASKETBALL
COACHES IN THE COUNTRY.
>> Gretchen: THERE IS IT A
INTERESTING STORY TO TELL YOU
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED IN
NEWTOWN.
GUN SALES ARE UP THIS MORNING
AT WALMART.
>> Gretchen: THAT IS THE
CIVILIAN VERSION OF THE
ASSAULT RIFLE USED GUY GI'S IN
IRAQ AND STAN STAN I WANT TO
MAKE SURE I HAVE THE RIGHT
NAMES OF THEM HERE.
THE QUESTION NOW IS, WALMART
STOPPED SELLING THESE.
THEY SAW THERE WAS A ON LINE
SURGE, FRENZY FOR PEOPLE TO
GET THEIR HANDS ON THE GUNS
AND MANY PEOPLE THE QUESTION
WHY DO PEOPLE NEED ASSAULTS IN
THO THIS COUNTRY.
>> Steve: SO MANY DEMOCRATS
ARE TALK BEING GUN
RESTRICTIONS.
LAST WEEKEND COLORADO STATE
SET A NEW RECORD FOR SINGLE
DAY BACKGROUND CHECKS IN THE
NORTHWEST ARMORY.
AND KEEP IN MIND THIS IS
SATURDAY THE DAY AFTER NEWTOWN
AND IN SOUTHWEST OHIO,
BUILDING WAS FULL AND THEY HAD
A LINE OF 400 PEOPLE OUT OF
THE DOOR.
KEEP IN MIND THERE WAS A BAND
THAT WENT INTO AFFECT BACK IN
1994.
AND ALLEN GOTLEY WASED LAST
NIGHT ON THE O'REILY SHOW
WHETHER IT DID MUCH IN THE
SLOWING DOWN OF THE CARNAGE.
LISTEN TO THIS.
>> WE BANNED THEM ONE TIME IN
1994.
AND LOOK AT THE STUDY ON THE
BAN THAT WAS DONE IN NINE 99
AND A UNIVERSITY STUDY PRO GUN
RIGHTS THOUGHT.
IT SHOWED IT HAD NO IMPACT ON
LOWERS HOMICIDE RATES AND NO
IMPACT ON LOWERS MASS MURDERS
AND NO IMPACT THAT A VICTIM
WAS SHOT WITH.
THE TRUTH DIDN'T WORK.
WHAT HAPPENED?
WE HAD A 10 YEAR SUPPLY AND IT
IS DEBATED ON AND YOU KNOW
WHEN IT WAS ENACT BECAME
AFFECTED.
WE'LL SEE THIS, THIS TIME,
TOO>> Brian: PRESIDENT OBAMA
WAS TOLD TO COME UP WITH A
LIST OF PROPOSAL AND WE KNOW
THAT ANDREW CUOMO HAD A PRESS
CONFERENCE SENATOR WARNER AND
SENATOR MANCHIN SAID WE CAN
LOOK AT REEVALUATING THE
WEAPONS.
>> Gretchen: THINGS HAVE
CHANGED SINCE 1994.
WE HAVE SEEN MORE MASS
SHOOTINGS AND I DON'T KNOW IF
THAT STATISTIC IF I AM LOOKING
AT IT IF I GO WITH A 1994
PARTICULAR NOW WE ARE IN 2012.
IT WOULD BE INTERESTING TO SEE
IF IT WAS ALL ASSAULT WEAPONS
THRARP USED AND NUMBER THREE
FOR ME.
EVEN IF YOU ARE FOR GUN
RIGHTS, IS THERE A DIFFERENCE
BEING FOR GUN RIGHTS AND
AGAINST ASSAULT WEAPONS.
>> Brian: I LOOK AT THE MENTAL
ILLNESS SEGMENT WITH KEITH
ABLOW.
AND WHETHER THEY SHOULD BE OUT
THERE OR NOT.
GO DEBATE IT BUT THE MENTAL
CAPACITY AND THE PEOPLE WHO
ARE KILLING PEOPLE WITH IT.
AND THEY ARE TOTALLY
UNBALANCED.
>> Gretchen: WHAT DO YOU NEED
ASSAULT WEAPONS FOR.
>> Steve: WHEN YOU LOOK AT THE
NUMBER OF RIFLES.
THERE WERE 12,000 MURDERS LAST
YEAR.
HOW MANY WERE COMMITTED WITH
RIFLES?
300.
HOW MANY MASS SHOOTINGS ARE
DONE WITH ASSAULT.
I DON'T OWN GUNS AND SO I
DON'T KNOW WHAT THEY ARE USED
FOR AND I HAVE HEARD THES THAT
YOU CAN BE PRO GUN AND AGAINST
ASSAULT WEAPONS.
AND WHAT DO YOU NEED AN
ASSAULT WEAPON FOR.
>> Steve: WHAT DO YOU.
FRIENDS AT FOX NEWS.COM.
IS IT TIME TO CHANGELET LAWS
ON THE BOOKS OR IS THERE LAWS
THAT ARE NOT USED AS THEY
SHOULD BE.
>> Brian: THE GOVERNMENT IS
PUTTING TOGETHER A BILL TO
HELP SANDY VICTIMS.
NOT IF THEY ARE PUTTING MONEY
TO STATES NOT AFFECTED BY
ALASKA CAN YOU SAY CUBA?
WHY ARE THEY WINDING UP WITH
MONEY.
AND WHAT HAPPENS WHEN SUPER
LIBERALS LIKE WARREN BUFFET.
ONLY THEY KNOW HOW TO AVOID AT
ING IT.
GOOD MORNING, STU.
WE UNDERSTAN
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
Progresso.
In what world do potatoes,
bacon and cheese
add up to 100 calories?
Your world.
♪
[ whispers ]
Real bacon...
Creamy cheese...
100 calories...
[ Chef ] Ma'am
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
>> Gretchen: BERNY MADOFF'S
YOUNGER BROTHER WILL BE
SENTENCED.
BUT HE WANTS TO REMAIN FREE
UNTIL AFTER THE GRAN
DAUGHTER'S BAR MITSZAH.
NAND 24 HOURS BEFORE THE
STORM, ONE MAN TRY TOD GET HIS
CAR TO EVACUATE HIS WHEELCHAIR
BOUND DAUGHTER BUT ACCOUNTED -
COULD NOT.
>> Steve: BILLIONAIRES LIKE
WARREN BUFFET AND BILL GATES
AND GEORGE SOROS ARE
PETITIONING CONGRESS SAYING WE
BELIEVE IT IS RIGHT TO HAVE A
SIGNIFICANT TAX ON LARGE
ESTATES WHEN THEY ARE PASSED
ON TO THE NEXT GENERATION.
ARE THEY LOOKING OUT FOR YOUR
CHILDREN OR MAKING A QUICK
BUCK.
SNOW, RICH E. PEOPLE.
WARERN BUFFET AND GEORGE SOROS
ABOUT BILL GATE'S FATHER.
THEY ARE SUPER RICH PEOPLE WHO
SAY YOU SHOULD PAY A HIGHER
ESTATE TAX.
WE WON'T BUT YOU SHOULD.
>> Steve: CURRENTLY IT IS 35
PERCENT AND WOULD LIKE TO SEE
IT GO UP TO 50.
>> THEY WANT A TWO MILLION
DOLLAR EXCLUSION .
EVERY DOLLAR IN YOUR ESTATE
ABOVE TWO MILLION WILL BE
TAXED AT A 45 PERCENT RATE
WHEN YOU DIE OR PASS AWAY.
THAT IS --
THAT CATCHES A LOT OF PEOPLE.
500,000 FAMILY FARMS WOULD BE
CAUGHT.
THESE PEOPLE WILL NOT PAY.
THEY HAVE AN ARMY OF ESTATE
ACCOUNTANTS AND LAWYERS TO
PROTECT THEM.
FOCUS IN ON WARREN BUFFET.
ON TWO 41S.
NUMBER ONE HE WILL GIVE TO THE
BILL AND LINDA GATES 10S OF
BILLIONS AND HE GETS A
DEDUCTION FOR THAMP HE WILL
NOT PAY THE TAX HOLD ON A
SECOND.
HE RUNS SENLIFE INSURANCE
COMPANIES WITHIN HIS BERK
SHINE HATH AWAY COMPANY PEOPLE
WHO HAVE ASSETS, BUT MAYBE
THEY HAVE SOME ASSETS AND THEY
ARE TRYING TO DO THE SAME
THING DOES THE PRESIDENT MAKE
MONEY ON THE PLANS?
>> WHAT YOU ARE SUGGESTING
THAT THEY SPEED UP CHARITABLE
DEDUCTIONS AND PACK AS MUCH IN
THE YEAR OF 2012 AND YOU MIGHT
GET A BETTER TAX DEDUCTIONS
AND THAT IS NOT GETTING MORE
MONEY TO THE TREASURY.
THAT IS ACTUALLY TAKING MONEY
AWAY FROM THE TREASURY.
IF THAT WERE TAKEN NEXT YEAR
YOU MAY MORE TAX.
>> Brian: WHY IS IT THAT
WARREN BUFFET CAN DO THIS.
ANYONE CAN DO THAT IF THEY ARE
MAKING OVER TWO MILLION
DOLLARS.
AND YOU FEEL LIKE YOU ARE
SUBJECTED TO THE NEW ESTATE
TAX LEVEL YOU CAN DO THE SAME
THING.
>> Steve: YOU CAN HIRE
YOURSELF A ESTATE TAX PLANNER
AND FORMULATE A WAY OF
AVOIDING THE STATE TAX.
99 PERCENT OF THE PEOPLE DO
THAT AND UNFORTUNATE LOW IT IS
DIFFICULT TO DO WHEN YOU HAVE
A MAUL BUSINESS OR FAMILY FARM
.
>> Steve: THE THING ABOUT THE
DEATH TAX.
YOU ARE TAXED THE SECOND AND
THIRD TIME.
YOU MAKE MONEY AND WHEN YOU
DIE TAKE ANOTHER BITE OF THE
APPLE.
>> Steve:
>> WHY SHOULDN'T WE PASS IT
ALONG TO THE CHILDREN.
WHY CAN'T WE DO THAT.
>> Steve: I AM WITH YOU.
>> IS THIS AMERICA OR WHAT?
>> Steve: IT IS BUT GETH
HARDER TO SEE THAT.
WILL ARE ARE -- >> WARREN
BUFFET DONE WANT INHERITANCE.
WE MUST HAVE A HIGHER STATE
TAX.
>> Steve: AND STE STUART
DIDN'T WANT A EUROPEAN LIFE
STYLE.
HE DEFECTED.
>> I AM GETTING HOTURN THE
COLLAR.
>> Brian: I CAN SEE THE VARNEY
KIDS ARE CHEERING IN THE GREEN
ROOM AND WANT YOUR MONEY AND
MAKING SURE THEY WILL NOT GIVE
UP 45 PERCENT.
>> THREE OF THEM ARE WATCHING.
>> Gretchen: EVEN THOUGH YOU
DEFECTED.
I AM SO GLAD YOU BROUGHT YOUR
ACCENT.
>> Steve: THANK YOU, STEWART.
AND GET THIS.
THE CURE TO CANCER MAY ROBBERY
IN OUR REFRIGERATOR ALL ALONG.
DETAILS.
>> Gretchen: THEN THE
GOVERNMENT PUTTING TOGETHER A
BILL TO HELP HURRICANE SANDY
VICTIMS.
WHY IS IT FILLED WITH CASH FOR
ALASKA ANDINE CUBA.
THAT'S COMING UP.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
>> Brian: LAST THING YOU WANT
TO SEE IS EXTREME WEATHER
EXTREME WASTE BY THE
GOVERNMENT.
THAT'S WHAT WE ARE GETTING IN
THE LAST HURRICANE SANDY
RELIEF BILL .
>> Gretchen: ONLY A TRACTION
IS DEDICATED.
THE REST GOES TO GOVERNMENT
PROJECTS THAT HAVE NOTHING TO
DO WITH THE STORM.
HOW CAN THAT BE?
COUNCILMAN, WHY IS ALASKA
FISHERIES GETTING $150 AND
U.S. BASES.
>> WE HAVE A SPENDING CAP AND
UNDER THE BUDGET AGREEMENT THE
GOVERNMENT IT EXCEPT IN CASES
OF EMERGENCY.
THIS IS EPPED RUN AROUND THE
BUDGET PROCESS .
WE DON'T JUST HAVE FISHERIES.
WE HAVE AMTRAK SUBSIDY FOR 366
MILLION.
AND THAT IS IN ADDITION TO THE
SUBSIDIES WE GIVE THEM AND
ONLY 23 MILLION HAS TO DO WITH
THE HURRICANE.
>> Brian: IT IS A STRUGGLE
FROM THE GITGO AND REPUBLICANS
SAY THERE IS NO OFF SETS AND
WE THROW MONEY AT CATAC
STROPHIES.
>> WE DON'T KNOW WHERE THE
MONEY IS GOING.
THERE IS FISHERIES WHICH IS
ONE ISSUE ALL OF THE MONEY IN
AGGREGATE IS HALF OF THE MONEY
REQUESTED BY THE STATES FOR
DIRECT AID.
WED 80 BILLION IN TOTAL RELIEF
PACKAGES TO DEAL WITH ON THE
GROUND.
60 BILLION IS NOT DIRECT AID
20 BILLION OF FLUFF.
>> Gretchen: SENATORS IN
ALASKA WOULD SAY AFTER THE
SUNSHINE SUNSHINE HIT, -
TSNAMI HIT WE DIDN'T GET
ENOUGH MONEY AND THEY ARE
TRYING TO TACK ON THE EXPENSES
TO YOU.
IS THAT THE WAY POLITICS WORK.
>> THAT'S WHY WE HAVE A TAX
BURDEP AND LOOK, I HAVE NO
DOUBT THAT THE FISHERIES WERE
INJURED IN THE TSUNAMI >>
Brian: BUT LET THEM FIGHT FOR
THAT.
>> THIS SHOULDN'T BE IN
EMERGENCY RELIEF.
NOT REGULAR SEND APPROXIMATING
BUT EMERGENCY RELIEF.
WE ARE ONLY GETTING HALF OF
WHAT WED FOR NEW YORK AND NEW
JERSEY FOR THE ENTIRE AREA.
>> Brian: MAIN AREA.
>> CLEARLY THE COAST LINE.
WE HAVE HOMES AND PROPERS AND
BUSINESSS AND PUBLIC SPACES
FROM DOWN IN THE DELMAR ALL
THE WAY UP AND ALL OF THOSE
NEED SERIOUS REPAIR.
BREEZY POINT IS DEVASTATED.
YOU ARE TALKING ABOUT 100
HOMES AND NOT A BIT OF THEM
LEFT.
NO OFFENSE.
THE FISH IN ALASKA NOT MY
PRIORITY WHEN I HAVE PEOPLE
OUT OF HOME IN MY DRICT OR ANY
OTHER DRICTS.
>> Gretchen: YOU HAVE TO
WONDER WHY TWO MILLION GOING
TO THE MYTHSONIAN.
>> HOW IS THAT EMERGENCY
SPENDING AND THIS COMES BACK
WITH THE PROBLEM WITH DEALING
WITH THE PROBLEMS IN PIECE
MEAL.
WE HAVE TO LOOK AT THE BUDGET
AS A BIG PICTURE.
>> Brian: IN THE MIDDLE OF THE
STORM FIGHTING TO GET BACK ON
THE FEET.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Gretchen: COMING UP NEXT ON
THE RUN DOWN.
WILL IT BE THE SAME OLD STORY.
THAT GUY DOESN'T WANT TO SHAVE
HIS YEARED.
>> Brian: DOCTORS TOLD THIS
MOM WHO WOULDN'T MAKE IT AND
SHE RECEIVED NEW ORGANS, HERE
NEXT.
HI, I'M PHIL MICKELSON.
I'VE BEEN FORTUNATE TO WIN
ON GOLF'S BIGGEST STAGES.
BUT WHEN JOINT PAIN
AND STIFFNESS
FROM PSORIATIC ARTHRITIS HIT,
EVEN THE SMALLEST THINGS
BECAME DIFFICULT.
I FINALLY UNDERSTOOD WHAT
SERIOUS JOINT PAIN IS LIKE.
I TALKED TO MY RHEUMATOLOGIST
AND HE PRESCRIBED Enbrel.
Enbrel CAN HELP RELIEVE
PAIN, STIFFNESS,
AND STOP JOINT DAMAGE.
BECAUSE Enbrel, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS,
SOMETIMES FATAL EVENTS
INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS,
LYMPHOMA, OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING Enbrel,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START Enbrel IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILEN Enbrel, YOU
EXPERICE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING, OR PALENESS.
[ Phil ]
GET BACK TO THE THINGS
THAT MATTER MOST.
ASK YOUR RHEUMATOLOGIST
IF Enbrel IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
[ Doctor ]
Enbrel, THE NUMBER ONE
BIOLOG MEDICINE
PRESCRIBED BY RHEUMATOLOGISTS.
This reduced sodium soup
says it mahelp
lower cholesterol,
how does it work?
You just he to eat it as part
of your heart healthy diet.
Step 1. Eat the soup.
All those
veggies and beans,
that's what may help
lower your cholesterol and --
Well that's easy
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a
Droid Incredible 4G LTE
by HTC for $49.99.
>> Gretchen: GOOD MORNING,
EVERYBODY.
TODAY IS TUESDAY, DECEMBER 18,
2012.
I'M GRETCHEN CARLSON.
THANKS FORBE SHARING YOUR TIME
WITH US TODAY.
IT'S NOW BEEN FOUR DAYS SINCE
THE TRAGEDY THAT SHOOK THE
NATION.
STUDENTS OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, THEY'RE GOING TO
HEAD BACK TO SCHOOL TODAY.
THIS AS POLICE FOCUS ON THE
KILLER'S COMPUTER.
WE'RE LIVE IN CON CONDITION WITH
SOME OF THE HERO STORIES COMING
UP.
>> Brian: ONE MOM COMMENTS
FIRING UP THE COUNTRY.
SHE SAYS I AM ADAM LANZA'S
MOTHER.
HER VERY HONEST STORIES ABOUT
DEALING WITH KIDS WITH MENTAL
ILLNESS AND HER PERSONAL STORY
COMING YOUR WAY.
>> Steve: AND SHE WAS GIVEN
MONTHS TO LIVE.
NOW SHE WILL BE HOME FOR
CHRISTMAS AFTER NOT ONE, NOT
TWO, BUT THREE ORGAN
TRANSPLANTS.
THIS MIRACLE MOTHER HERE THIS
HOUR.
"FOX & FRIENDS" HOUR TWO FOR
TUESDAY STARTS RIGHT NOW.
>> Gretchen: WELCOME, EVERYBODY.
HOPEFULLY AS WE MOVE CLOSER TO
THE WONDERFUL CELEBRATION OF
CHRISTMAS, WE CAN BRING YOU MORE
OF THESE KIND OF MIRACLE GOOD
NEWS STORIES BECAUSE SOMETIMES
WE CAN GET MYERED DOWN IN THE
TRAGIC NEWS THAT HAPPENED LAST
WEEK IT'S GOOD TO HAVE AN
UPLIFTING REASON TO MOVE ON WITH
YOUR DAY.
>> Brian: TALK ABOUT THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
>> Steve: CHRISTMAS IS EXACTLY
ONE WEEK AWAY FROM TODAY.
>> Gretchen: IT'S ANOTHER
EMOTIONAL DAY IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT R TWO MORE FUNERALS
WILL BE HELD FOR THE YOUNG
VICTIMS OF THAT TRAGEDY.
ONE FOR SIX-YEAR-OLD JAMES.
HE WAS CALLED JAY.
HIS FAMILY SAYS HE LOVED RECESS
AND MATH AND CALLED HIM THEIR
NUMBERS GUY.
THE OTHERS WERE SIX-YEAR-OLD
JESSICA RICO WHO LOVED
EVERYTHING ABOUT HORSES AND
PLAYING WITH HER LITTLE
BROTHERS.
AND AS THE COMMUNITY MOURNS,
STUDENTS AT OTHER NEWTOWN
SCHOOLS WILL HEAD BACK TO CLASS
FOR THE FIRST TIME AND THAT'S
WHERE WE FIND PETER DOOCY THIS
MORNING WHO HAS BEEN IN NEWTOWN
FOR THE BETTER PART OF THE LAST
FOUR DAYS.
GOOD MORNING.
>> GOOD MORNING, GRETCHEN.
AND STUDENTS WHO ESCAPED SANDY
HOOK ON FRIDAY WON'T HAVE TO GO
BACK TO SCHOOL TODAY AND THEY
WOULD NOT HAVE TO GO BACK TO
THAT BUILDING, AT LEAST NOT FOR
A WHILE.
NO TIME THAT ANYBODY WILL
CONFIRM TO US.
THEY MIGHT NEVER GO BACK.
YESTERDAY MOVING TRUCKS WITH
POLICE ESCORTS TOOK FURNITURE
AND BROUGHT IT TO CHALK HILL
MIDDLE SCHOOL.
CHALK HILL WAS BUILT IN THE
'60S, BUT IT JUST WENT OFF LINE
LAST YEAR BECAUSE ATTENDANCE
DROPPED.
TO EASE THE TRANSITION FOR THE
STUDENTS TO THIS NEW SPACE,
OFFICIALS ARE TRYING TO MAKE
THINGS AS FAMILIAR AS THEY CAN.
>> ED SANDY HOOK SCHOOL
FURNITURE FROM WHAT I UNDERSTAND
WILL BE AGE AND WEIGHT
APPROPRIATE.
IT'S AN ENORMOUS PROVE.
THE HEALING AND BACK TO NORMALCY
FEELING THAT WILL HOPEFULLY COME
FROM IT IS WORTH EVERY EFFORT.
>> PARENTS ARE NOT GOING TO BE
ALLOWED TO SEE THE INSIDE OF
CHALK HILL BEFORE IT OPENS FOR
SECURITY REASONS.
BUT WE'RE TOLD THAT WHENEVER IT
DOES OPEN, POLICE IN RED
JACKETS, SO THAT THEY'RE EASILY
IDENTIFIABLE, WILL THEREBY TO
CONSOLE STUDENTS BURKS ALSO
CHECK I.D.'S AND MAKE SURE THAT
THINGS ARE SAFE.
WE'RE TOLD THAT THE TIME THAT
THE POLICE WILL BE THERE IS OPEN
ENDED.
THERE IS NO DATE THEY WILL BE
THERE.
AS LONG AS IT TAKES FOR PAINTS
AND STUDENTS AND TEACHERS TO
FEEL COMFORTABLE.
WE'RE TOLD THERE IS NO WORD ON
WHEN STUDENTS WHO ARE IN SANDY
HOOK WILL GO BACK TO SCHOOL.
I'VE SPOKEN TO SOME PARENTS
WHOSE STUDENTS SURVIVED AND THEY
THINK IT SHOULD BE AFTER THE
HOLIDAY BREAK.
BACK TO YOU.
>> Steve: PETER, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
IT'S IMPORTANT THAT THEY ARE
GOING TO MAKE SURE THAT THE
SECURITY PERSONNEL ARE CLEARLY
LABELED SECURITY BECAUSE WE'VE
BEEN READING SOME OF THE STORIES
ABOUT SOME OF THE CHILDREN WHO
WERE IN THE SCHOOL THAT DAY AND
DID SURVIVE.
EVERY TIME THERE IS A LOUD
NOISE, THEY GET FREAKED OUT.
WHEN THEY SEE A STRANGER, THEY
DON'T KNOW WHY THE STRANGER IS
THERE.
EVERYBODY HAS A LEVEL OF ANXIETY
THAT IS SO HIGH, IT'S GOOD THAT
THEY'RE GOING TO BE GOING TO A
SCHOOL AND PICK UP THE PIECES AT
CHALK HILL.
BUT LIKE IN THAT STORY THERE,
YOU NEED THE APPROPRIATE SIZE
FURNITURE.
REMEMBER THE LITTLE CHAIRS FOR
KINDERGARTEN AND FIRST GRADE
BECAUSE THIS WAS A MIDDLE
SCHOOL.
EVERYTHING IS BIG SIZE.
>> Gretchen: WHEN I WENT TO PICK
UP MY DAUGHTER YESTERDAY AT
SCHOOL, I NOTICED THE EXTRA
SECURITY GUARDS AND VERY WELL
MARKED WITH YELLOW JACKETS.
IT WAS INTERESTING BECAUSE SHE
GOT IN THE CALL AND SAID MOMMY,
I FEEL SAFE BECAUSE WE HAVE MANY
MORE POLICE OFFICERS NOW.
IS THAT THE WORLD WE'RE GOING TO
LIVE IN NOW, THAT OUR KIDS ARE
GOING TO HAVE POLICE OFFICERS
OUTSIDE OF THEIR SCHOOLS ON A
FULL-TIME BASIS?
I GUESS WE'LL FIND OUT.
>> Brian: FOUR MINUTES AFTER THE
HOUR.
LET'S TALK ABOUT ONE TEACHER WE
TOUCHED ON YESTERDAY.
27 YEARS OLD, SINGLE WOMAN WHO
DID HEROIC THINGS.
FOR EXAMPLE, IN HER CLASSROOM
WHEN SHE HEARD THE CLASSROOM
ACROSS THE HALL, EVIDENTLY THE
GUNMAN CAME IN TO HER AND THEY
SAID R ARE THE KIDS?
SHE SAID DOWN THE HALL AT THE
AUDITORIUM, AT WHICH TIME WE
UNDERSTAND SOP OF THE KIDS WHO
WERE HIDING IN CLOSET RAN OUT.
THE GUNMAN WENT TO SHOOT THE
CHILDREN.
SHE DOVE IN FRONT OF THEM AND AT
THAT TIME, SHE PROBABLY SAVED
HALF THE STUDENTS?
HER CLASS.
HALF DID LOSE THEIR LIVES,
INCLUDING JACK, WHO YOU SAW PUT
TO REST YESTERDAY.
THOSE SIX KIDS, WHERE DID THEY
GO AS THEY RAN OUT?
IT TURNS OUT WE KNOW EXACTLY
WHERE THEY WENT.
REAL QUICK B THAT HEROIC
TEACHER?
WE TALKED TO THAT TEACHER'S
ROOMMATE WHEN THEY WERE BOTH
FELLOW TEACHERS AS THEY WERE IN
COLLEGE TOGETHER.
LET'S LISTEN.
>> SHE LOVED HER JOB AND SHE
LOVED THEM AND I WAS NOT AT ALL
SURPRISED SHE WOULD DO THIS,
THAT SHE WOULD PROTECT THEM AND
GIVE HER LIFE TO SAVE THEIRS.
HEART BREAKING, BUT I KNEW
THAT'S VICKY.
THAT'S WHAT SHE WOULD DO.
THESE KIDS WERE HER LIFE.
>> Steve: THEY BOTH GRADUATED --
THAT WAS A YOUNG WOMAN NAMED
KRISTEN.
THEY BOTH GRADUATED IN 2008 FROM
EASTERN CONNECTICUT STATE
UNIVERSITY.
BEING A TEACHER IS ALL THAT
VICKY SOTO EVER WANTED TO DO.
HER SISTER, CAYLEE WAS FEATURED
IN NEWSPAPERS ALL ACROSS THE
COUNTRY.
YOU SEE THAT PICTURE STANDING
OUTSIDE THE SCHOOL.
SHE IS ON THE PHONE.
SHE DOES NOT KNOW FOR SURE
WHETHER OR NOT HER SISTER --
DOESN'T KNOW IF HER SISTER VICKY
IS DEAD OR ALIVE.
SHE'S SIMPLY BEGGING FOR
INFORMATION.
SHE SAYS SEEING THAT PHOTO, IT'S
LIKE REMINDER OF THAT MOMENT ALL
OVER.
IT KILLS.
>> Gretchen: BRIAN WAS JUST
ALLUDING TO WHERE THE SIX
CHILDREN ENDED UP WHO MANAGED TO
ESCAPE.
JEAN ROSEN HAD BEEN OUT FOR
BREAKFAST.
CAME HOME TO HIS HOUSE.
HERE HE IS FINDING OUT ABOUT THE
TRAGIC NEWS AND SEES THESE SIX
CHILDREN STANDING ON HIS LAWN.
HE THOUGHT THEY WERE PART OF A
SCHOOL PLAY, MAYBE IT WAS A SKIT
THEY WERE DOING.
SUDDENLY THE KIDS WERE CRYING
ASK TELLING HIM OUR TEACHER IS
DEAD.
WE CAN'T GO BACK TO SCHOOL.
WHAT DID HE DO?
HE BROUGHT THEM INSIDE HIS HOME
FOR SAFETY.
EVENTUALLY A SCHOOL BUS DRIVER
CAME IN, ABLE TO HELP HIM
IDENTIFY THE CHILDREN, GAVE THEM
JUICE AND STUFFED ANIMALS.
CALLED THEIR PARENTS.
THE SADDEST PART TO ME ABOUT
THIS STORY IS THAT LATER ON, A
PARENT CAME TO HIS HOUSE AND
SAID, I UNDERSTAND THAT YOU HAVE
SOME CHILDREN HERE WHO SURVIVED.
WAS MY CHILD HERE?
AND HE, UNFORTUNATELY H TO TELL
HER NO.
>> Steve: THERE IS ONE OTHER
STORY THAT I SAW THIS MORNING IN
THE STORY REGARDING VICKY SOTO.
THAT IS HER TEACHER'S AIDE,
52-YEAR-OLD WOMAN NAMED ANN
MARIE MURPHY.
WHEN THE SHOOTING STARTED, SHE
GRABBED ONE OF THE KIDS AND, IN
FACT, DYLAN HOCKNY, WAS FOUND IN
HER ARMS, AND THE FAMILY ISSUED
A STATEMENT -- DYLAN WAS
AUTISTIC AS ADAM LANZA WAS.
DYLAN'S FAMILY ISSUED A
STATEMENT YESTERDAY.
WE TAKE GREAT COMFORT IN KNOWING
THAT DYLAN WAS NOT ALONE WHEN HE
DIED, BUT WAS WRAPPED IN THE
ARMS OF HIS AMAZING AIDE, ANN
MARIE MURPHY.
>> Brian: WHAT THOSE KIDS SAW,
IT MUST BE ABSOLUTELY HORRIFIC
AND UNFORTUNATELY, WE DO KNOW
ONE OF THE KIDS SAID, THE MAN
CAME INTO OUR CLASSROOM AND HE
HAD A BIG GUN AND A LITTLE GUN.
SO IT LOOKS LIKE THEY RAN AFTER
SEEING HIM AND WE KNOW THAT
RIGHT NOW THERE ARE TWO PEOPLE
WHO SURVIVED AFTER BEING SHOT.
THEY PROBABLY WILL HAVE MORE OF
THESE STORIES.
>> Gretchen: ONE OF THE BIG
TOPICS OF DISCUSSION IS MENTAL
ILLNESS AND HOW WE HANDLE IT IN
THIS SOCIETY AND WHETHER WE'RE
DOING ENOUGH.
PRETTY MUCH THE ANSWER FOR THAT
IS PROBABLY NO.
ONE MOM DECIDED VERY BRAVELY TO
WRITE A BLOG ABOUT HER PERSONAL
SITUATION WITH HER TEENAGE SON
WHO SHE'S CALLING MICHAEL IN
THIS PARTICULAR ARTICLE.
I HAVE TO TELL YOU, IT'S HEART
WRENCHING TO READ THIS ENTIRE
BLOG TO UNDERSTAND WHAT THIS
MOTHER GOES THROUGH ON A DAILY
BASIS, FEARING FOR HER LIFE.
SHE SAYS AT ONE MOMENT HE'S
FINE, THE NEXT MOMENT HE'S
THREATENING TO KILL THE ENTIRE
FAMILY.
>> Steve: THE BLOG IS ENTITLED
"I AM ADAM LANZA'S MOTSHE DOES D
SHE USES THE PSEUDONYM MICHAEL,
WAS 13 YEARS OLD, HAS MENTAL
PROBLEMS.
THEY DON'T KNOW WHAT HIS PROBLEM
IS, EXCEPT, FOR INSTANCE,
GRETCH, YOU ALLUDED TO SOME OF
THE EXCERPTS, MICHAEL PULLED A
KNIFE AND THREATENED TO KILL ME
AND THEN HIMSELF AND I ASKED HIM
TO RETURN HIS OVERDUE LIBRARY
BOOKS.
HE IS SEVEN AND NINE-YEAR-OLD
SIBLINGS KNEW THE SAFETY PLAN.
RAN TO THE CAR AND LOCK THE
DOOR.
HE CONTINUED TO SCREAM INSULTS
AND THREATEN TO KILL OR HURT ME.
>> Brian: SHE SAYS AT THIS
POINT, SHE'S STRONGER THAN HIM.
WHAT HAPPENS WHEN HE GETS OLDER?
HE SAYS, I'M HEARING THIS STORY
BECAUSE I AM ADAM LANZA'S
MOTHER, I AM DYLAN KLEBOLD AND
ERIC HARRIS, I AM SAYING WHO I
DON'T EVEN KNOW HOW TO SAY.
>> Gretchen: THE VIRGINIA TECH
GUY.
>> Brian: THESE BOYS AND THESE
MOTHERS NEED HELP IN THE WAKE OF
ANOTHER NATIONAL TRAGEDY.
IT'S EASY TO TALK ABOUT GUN, BUT
IT'S TIME TO TALK ABOUT MENTAL
ILLNESS.
HOW DO YOU GET ADDITIONAL HELP
FOR YOUR KID?
THEY NEED TO DO SOMETHING FOR
YOU TO GET LAW ENFORCEMENT AND
THE MEDICAL COMMUNITY.
>> Gretchen: SHE SAYS LOOK, I
CAN GO AND I CAN TURN HIM IN ON
A FRIDAY AND HE CAN GET NEW MEDS
AND BE OKAY ON MONDAY OF THE BUT
TUESDAY, HE'S BACK WITH A KNIFE.
IMAGINE LIVING A LIFE LIKE THAT.
SHE IS NOT ALONE AND WHO IS
THERE TO HELP HER AND WHAT DOES
THIS SAY ABOUT WHERE WE ARE IN
OUR SOCIETY WHERE MENTAL
ILLNESS?
KEEP IN MIND, THIS GUY WHO DID
THIS HORRIBLE TRAGEDY ON FRIDAY
HAD NEVER BEEN ARRESTED FOR A
CRIME.
THIS IS A CASE IN MANY
SITUATIONS IN OUR SOCIETY NOW,
I'M THINKING ABOUT DOMESTIC
VIOLENCE.
UNTIL SOMEBODY DOES SOMETHING OR
SOMEBODY IS DEAD, PEOPLE DON'T
DO ANYTHING ABOUT IT.
>> Steve: THE POINT OF HER BLOG
IS THAT UNLESS THE KID GOES TO
JAIL AND A 13-YEAR-OLD, SHE
SAYS, DOES NOT BELONG IN JAIL,
HERE IN THE UNITED STATES, THERE
ARE SIMPLY NOT MANY OPTIONS FOR
CHILDREN WHO ARE CHALLENGED.
>> Gretchen: YOUR OTHER
HEADLINES.
DEVELOPING STORY FOR YOU.
RICHARD ANGLE AND HIS CREW FREED
AFTER BEING KIDNAPPED AND HELD
CAPTIVE IN SYRIA FOR FIVE DAYS.
THEY WERE DRIVING IN WHAT THEY
THOUGHT WAS REBEL-CONTROLLED
AREA WHEN A GROUP OF 15 GUNMEN
WEARING SKI MASKS JUMPED OUT AND
PULLED THEM OUT OF THEIR CAR.
THEY PUT THE THREE MEN IN A
TRUCK AND BLINDFOLDED THEM.
THEY THREATENED TO KILL THEM
OVER AND OVER AGAIN, PRETENDED
TO SHOOT THEM.
FIRING THE GUN INTO THE AIR.
THE THREE MEN WERE EVENTUALLY
FREED BY REBELS.
THEY JUST ARRIVED SAFE FLEE
TURKEY.
HERE IS ANGLE IN HIS OWN WORDS.
>> WE WERE DRIVING IN SYRIA,
ABOUT FIVE DAYS AGO IN WHAT WE
THOUGHT WAS A REBEL-CONTROLLED
AREA.
WE WERE WITH SOME OF THE REBELS
AND AS WE WERE MOVING DOWN THE
ROAD, A GROUP OF GUNMEN JUST
LITERALLY JUMPED OUT OF THE
TREES AND BUSHES ON THE SIDE OF
THE ROAD.
THERE WERE PROBABLY 15 GUNMEN.
THEY WERE WEARING SKI MASKS,
HEAVILY ARMED.
THEY DRAGGED US OUT OF THE CAR.
THEY HAD A CONTAINER TRUCK
POSITIONED WAITING BY THE SIDE
OF THE ROAD.
THEY PUT US INTO THAT CONTAINER
TRUCK.
WE WERE WITH SOME GUNMEN, REBELS
WHO WERE ESCORTING US.
THEY EXECUTED ONE ON THE.  SO
THEN TOOK US TO A SERIES OF SAFE
HOUSES AND INTERROGATION PLACES
AND THEY KEPT US BLINDFOLDED,
BOUND.
WE WEREN'T PHYSICALLY BEATEN OR
TORTURED.
LOT OF PSYCHOLOGICAL TORTURED.
>> Gretchen: THEY SAID THEY
WOULD BRING THOME A HEZBOLLAH
STRONGHOLD WHERE THEY WOULD
EXCHANGE THEM FOR FIVE IRANIAN
AGENTSES.
QUITE A STORY.
>> Steve: THAT IS SUCH GOOD NEWS
BECAUSE HE'S BEEN MISSING FOR A
WHILE.
IT LOOKED GRIM.
BUT HE'S FREE.
>> Brian: AFTER THE SHOOTING,
WHAT DOES THE FUTURE OF GUNS IN
AMERICA?
PETER JOHNSON, JR. HERE LIVE
WITH AN INTERESTING PERSPECTIVE
NEXT.
>> Steve: THEN WE'VE BEEN
FOLLOWING THIS STORY.
EASY BACK OVENS FOR BOYS?
NOW HASBRO'S DECISION FINALLY
IN.
I LOVE THE HOLIDAYS.
AND WITH MY BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CREDIT CARD,
I LOVE 'EM EVEN MORE.
I EARN 1% CASH BACK EVERYWHERE,
EVERTIME.
2% ON GROCERIES.
3% ON GAS.
AUTOMATICALLY.
NO HOOPS TO JUMP THROUGH.
THAT'S 1% BACK ON...
[ toy robot sounds ]
2% ON PUMPN PIE.
AND APPLE.
3% BACK ON 4 TRIPS
TO THE AIRPORT.
IT'S AS EASY AS..
-[ man ] 1...
-[ woman ] 2...
[ woman ] 3.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CARD.
APPLY ONLINE OR AT
A BANK OF AMERICA NEAR YOU.
ER.
>> Gretchen: INVESTIGATION INTO
THE NEWTOWN SHOOTING FOCUSED ON
THE KILLER'S COMPUTER.
LET'S GO TO WNYW REPORTER ROBERT
POSER.
HI, ROBERT.
>> GOOD MORNING TO YOU AND GOOD
MORNING, EVERYBODY.
WE'RE STANDING IN THE MIDDLE OF
NEWTOWN AMIDST A GROWING
MEMORIAL FOR THE VICTIMS HERE OF
FRIDAY'S SHOOTING.
POLICE SAY THEY HAVE SEIZED A
SIGNIFICANT AMOUNT OF EVIDENCE
FROM THE HOME THAT 20-YEAR-OLD
ADAM LANZA SHARED WITH HIS
MOTHER, NANCY, IN NEWTOWN.
WHILE POLICE WOULD NOT
OFFICIALLY SPECIFY WHAT THAT
EVIDENCE IS, REPORTS SAY THAT
ONE PIECE OF EVIDENCE INCLUDE
HAS COMPUTER HARD DRIVE SEVERELY
DAMAGED FOR SOME REASON.
SO POLICE ARE FACING A CHALLENGE
GETTING USEFUL INFORMATION OFF
OF THAT HARD DRIVE.
ALSO YESTERDAY, POLICE TOLD US
THAT ACTUALLY TWO PEOPLE
SURVIVED THE SHOOTING INSIDE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND
NOT JUST ONE PERSON, AS
PREVIOUSLY THOUGHT.
ANOTHER MISCONCEPTION THAT
POLICE CLEARED UP WAS THAT IT
APPEARS AS THOUGH ADAM LANZA HAD
NO CONNECTION TO THE SCHOOL.
YOU'LL RECALL THAT THERE WERE
SOME INITIAL REPORTS THAT EITHER
HIS MOTHER WAS A TEACH THERE ARE
OR HE ATTENDED THERE.
BUT POLICE SAY LANZA DID NOT
HAVE ANY APPARENT CONNECTION TO
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
ALSO WE'RE LEARNING THIS
MORNING, ACCORDING TO THE
DANBURY NEWS TIMES, RIGHT NOW
POLICE HAVE NO EVIDENCE THAT
ADAM LANZA HAD ANY SORT OF
PRESCRIPTION MEDICATION FOR
MENTAL ILLNESS, BUT THAT WILL BE
PART OF THIS INVESTIGATION.
AN INVESTIGATION WE'RE TOLD THAT
COULD LAST WEEKS OR EVEN MONTHS.
THAT IS THE LATEST, LIVE FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT THIS
MORNING, ROBERT MOSES, FOX NEWS.
BACK TO YOU.
>> Gretchen: WOW.
LOOK AT ALL THOSE FLOWERS AROUND
ROBERT IN TRIBUTE TO ALL OF
THOSE CHILDREN AND ADULTS
KILLED.
THANKS, ROBERT.
STEVE?
>> Steve: THANKS.
SO WHAT IS THE FUTURE OF GUN
CONTROL IN THE UNITED STATES?
FOX NEWS LEGAL ANALYST PETER
JOHNSON, JR. IS HERE WITH
ANALYSIS.
WE ALREADY HAVE GUN CONTROL.
>> WE DO HAVE GUN CONTROL AND
SOME PEOPLE SAY WE NEED MORE GUN
CONTROL.
WE NEED MICRO STAMPING OF GUNS.
WE NEED THE ABILITY THAT EACH
TIME GUNS ARE PURCHASED, THAT
THERE BE REGISTRATION AND FOR
EACH PARTICULAR FIREARM THAT'S
PURCHASED, THE DISCUSSION OF
ACROSS STATE LAWS PURCHASING,
BRINGING FIREARMS.
BUT IT'S A BIGGER QUESTION THAN
GUN CONTROL.
THE WHITE HOUSE WILL PROBABLY
FRAME IT IN THE CONTEXT OF GUN
CONTROL.
IS VIOLENCE THE PRICE OF OUR
FREEDOM?
I DON'T THINK THAT'S AN
APPROPRIATE QUESTION.
THE QUESTION IS WHAT
CONVERSATION DO WE HAVE OUTSIDE
OF THE INTEREST GROUPS, OUTSIDE
OF THE POWER LOBBYING GROUPS ON
ALL SIDES, WHETHER IT'S PRO GUN,
ANTIGUN, WHETHER IT'S THE
ENTERTAINMENT INDUSTRY?
THE ENTERTAINMENT INDUSTRY,
THROUGH SOME BLOGGER, WENT AFTER
ME YESTERDAY.
THAT'S A POWERFUL LOBBY.
$17 BILLION A YEAR!
ARE WE WILLING TO ALLOW OUR
FUTURE AND OUR DECISION MAKING
TO BE IN THE HANDS OF PEOPLE
THAT ARE GIVING MONEY TO
CONGRESS?
SO I SAY PEOPLE HAVE THE RIGHT
UNDER THE SECOND AMENDMENT TO
OWN FIREARMS.
>> Steve: INDEED.
>> THE GOVERNMENT HAS THE RIGHT
TO REGISTER AND REGULATE THOSE
FIREARMS.
AT THE SAME TIME, WE NEED TO BE
THINKING ABOUT WHERE SHOULD WE
BE ALLOCATING LAW ENFORCEMENT
RESOURCES?
HOW CAN WE BETTER REGISTER?
HOW CAN ENTERTAINMENT STOP WITH
THE CULTURE OF DEATH IN TERMS OF
VIDEOS?
SO THERE IS A BIG, BIG
DISCUSSION THAT WE NEED TO HAVE
AT THIS PLACE, AT THE COUCH, IN
TOWN HALLS ACROSS AMERICA, JUST
LIKE WE DID WITH OBAMACARE, JUST
LIKE WE'VE DONE WITH OTHER
ISSUES IN OUR HISTORY.
PEOPLE HAVE TO DECIDE WHAT THEY
WANT GOING FORWARD.
>> Steve: BUT YOU WANT TO SEE
THE PEOPLE DECIDE AND TRY TO
EXCLUDE THE LOBBYISTS WHO HAVE A
LOT OF MONEY.
>> THE LOBBYIST ALSO ALWAYS BE
THERE.
THEY HAVE A TREMENDOUS AMOUNT OF
MONEY.
THEY INSTILL FEAR IN THE HEARTS
OF OUR CONGRESS.
ON EVERY SIDE OF THE ISSUE.
BUT IT'S ABOUT US AND IT'S ABOUT
OUR CHILDREN.
AND WE OWE IT TO OUR CHILDREN
WHO ARE LIVING.
WE OWE IT TO THESE CHILDREN WHO
DIED.
WE OWE IT TO OTHER PEOPLE WHO
HAVE DIED IN MASS VIOLENCE.
LET'S LOOK AT AK 47S AND AR 15S.
THE NUMBERS SHOW THAT IT'S A
SMALL PORTION OF THE DEATHS AND
VIOLENCE IN AMERICA.
BUT IT'S A HIGH PORTION, IT'S A
HIGH PROPORTION OF THE MASS
VIOLENCE EPISODES.
LET'S LOOK AT EVERYTHING IN A
DISPASSIONATE, SMART, OBJECTIVE
WAY THAT FORGETS AMERICANS AND
PROTECTS THE CONSTITUTION, BOTH.
>> Steve: IT'S A CONVERSATION
THAT STARTED ON FRIDAY.
>> ABSOLUTELY HAS.
>> Steve: ALL RIGHT.
PETER JOHNSON, JR.
THANK YOU.
NEXT UP, A MAJOR BREAKTHROUGH IN
THE FIGHT AGAINST CANCER.
COULD BE IN YOUR REFRIGERATOR
RIGHT NOW.
AND THIS WOMAN GIVEN MONTHS TO
LIVE.
NOW WILL BE HOME FOR CHRISTMAS
AFTER THREE ORGAN TRANSPLANTS.
THE MIRACLE MOM IS HERE LIVE
NEXT
>> Brian: THE PRESIDENT OF IRAQ
IN A COMA AFTER HAVING A STROKE.
DOCTORS UPDATING HIS CONDITION,
SAYING HE'S CRITICAL, BUT
STABLE.
THEY HAVE NOT DECIDED IF HE WILL
STAY IN BAGHDAD OR NOT, OR HE'LL
BE FLOWN TO ANOTHER COUNTRY FOR
TREATMENT.
HE'S 79 YEARS OLD AND NEVER
REALLY IN THAT GOOD OF SHAPE.
MAJOR NIDAL MALIK HASAN GOING
BEFORE A NEW MILITARY JUDGE
TODAY.
THE JUDGE COULD DECIDE TO
REVISIT EVERY RULING HER
PREDECESSOR MADE OVER THE LAST
17 MONTHS OF HEARINGS.
THE TRIAL HAS BEEN DELAYED OVER
AND OVER AND OVER AGAIN FOR THE
PAST THREE YEARS.
THE LAST DELAY WAS OVER DEMANDS
THAT HASAN BE FORCED TO SHAVE
HIS BEARD.
GRETCHEN?
>> Gretchen: THANK YOU, BRIAN.
FROM THE DAY SHE WAS BORN, OUR
NEXT GUEST HAS BEEN CALLED A
MEDICAL MIRACLE.
STEPHANIE WAS BORN WITH
CONGENITAL HEART DISEASE.
DOCTORS TOLD HER PARENTS SHE
WOULDN'T LIVE PAST THE AGE OF
TEN.
GUESS WHAT?
SHE JUST TURNED 38 ON SUNDAY AND
STEPHANIE HAS BEEN MARRIED FOR
14 YEARS, HAS TWO BEAUTIFUL
CHILDREN AND THIS RECENTLY
SURVIVED -- SHE RECENTLY
SURVIVED A TRIPLE ORGAN
TRANSPLANT.
THE FIRST OF ITS KIND IN THE
STATE OF GEORGIA.
JOINING ME FOR A GOOD NEWS STORY
TODAY, THE MIRACLE MOM,
STEPHANIE LYNNSTROM.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
>> GOOD MORNING, GRETCHEN.
>> Gretchen: WOW.
HOW FANTASTIC THAT YOU ARE GOING
TO BE HOME FOR CHRISTMAS WITH
YOUR HUSBAND AND YOUR TWO YOUNG
CHILDREN.
>> I KNOW.
I WAS AFRAID THAT I WOULDN'T
EVEN MAKE IT HOME BY CHRISTMAS
AND THEY RELEASED ME OCTOBER 23
WITH SOME FREQUENT CHECKUPS
EVERY MONTH OR SO.
I USUALLY TALK TO MY
COORDINATORS EVERY WEEK.
BUT IT SURE BEATS BEING IN THE
HOSPITAL FOR SO LONG.
>> Gretchen: NO DOUBT.
THIS SUMMER IN JULY THEY WERE
TELLING YOU THAT YOU WERE GOING
TO DIE.
YOUR FAMILY ACTUALLY CAME AND
SAID THEIR GOOD-BYES TO YOU.
WHAT HAPPENED?
>> THEY DID.
JULY 4, DR. BRIAN COGGEN TALKED
TO MY HUSBAND AND MY PARENTS AND
SAID THAT I HAD A COUPLE OF
DAYS, UP TO A WEEK, THAT IF
THINGS DID NOT TURN AROUND, IF I
DIDN'T GET THE ORGANS, THAT HE
WOULD BE HAVING A SERIOUS TALK
WITH MY HUSBAND, JOEL.
AND TWO DAYS LATER, THE ORGANS
CAME IN.
SO I TRULY BELIEVE THAT'S FROM
GOD AND HE JUST GAVE ME A
MIRACLE.
SO JULY 7 AND 8 IS WHEN I
RECEIVED THE HEART, THE LIVER
AND THE KIDNEY.
>> Gretchen: WOW.
SO YOU WERE BORN WITH A
CONGENITAL HEART DEFECT.
BUT YOU EVENTUALLY NEED TO HAVE
THOSE OTHER ORGANS.
WHY?
>> WELL, OVER THE YEARS, THEY
PERFORMED FOUR SURGERIES IN MY
CHILDHOOD THAT WERE MEDICALLY
NECESSARY BECAUSE I HAD ONE
BOTTOM CHAMBER OF MY HEART.
ONE VENTRICLE.
SO IT WAS A CORRECT PROCEDURE,
BUT THEY FOUND OVER THE YEARS
THAT THOSE PROCEDURES GAVE EXTRA
STRESS TO THE LIVER.
AND WITH ALL LIFETIME OF
MEDICINES AND TOXICITY BUILD-UP
IN THE LIVER.
SO THEY DIDN'T KNOW THAT WHEN MY
GENERATION WAS A KID, BUT THEY
FOUND IT IN PEOPLE IN THEIR 30S,
40S AND 50S NOW THAT THEY ARE
GOING STRAIGHT TO HEART AND
LIVER TRANSPLANTS AS THE LAST
TREATMENT OPTION.
AND BECAUSE I HAVE BEEN IN THE O
HAVE KIDNEY FAILURE WITH HAVING
DIALYSIS FOR TWO MONTHS PRIOR TO
THES ORGAN.
SO I DID HAVE THREE SYSTEMS
FAILING.
>> Gretchen: YOU ARE A MEDICAL
MIRACLE RIGHT NOW.
THE FIRST TIME THIS HAS BEEN
DONE IN GEORGIA WHERE YOU HAD
THESE THREE ORGANS TRANSPLANTED
AT THE SAME TIME.
>> YES.
>> Gretchen: AS YOU LOOK FORWARD
TO CHRISTMAS THIS YEAR, AND
WE'VE BEEN SEEING THESE
BEAUTIFUL PHOTOS OF YOU WITH
YOUR HUSBAND AND BEAUTIFUL
CHILDREN, FOUR AND SIX WHAT, IS
YOUR CHRISTMAS MESSAGE TO PEOPLE
WHO ARE WATCHING THIS MORNING?
>> I THINK IF YOU CAN LEARN
ANYTHING, THAT GOD HAS CREATED
ME, CREATED MY BODY AND FOR SOME
PURPOSE, I HOPE IT'S TO GIVE HIM
GLORY AND TO HELP OTHER PEOPLE
IN HEALTH CRISIS, THAT LIFE'S
NOT FAIR AND YOU CAN PICK UP THE
PIECES AND DO THE BEST YOU CAN
WITH WHAT YOU HAVE.
I ALSO ENCOURAGE DONATING
ORGANS, OF COURSE.
PEOPLE ARE DYING DAILY WAITING
FOR ORGANS AND THAT COULD HAVE
BEEN AND WOULD HAVE BEEN ME.
>> Gretchen: THAT'S RIGHT.
>> I'M JUST SO THANKFUL.
I DON'T TAKE THINGS FOR GRANTED
ANYMORE AT ALL.
>> Gretchen: OF COURSE NOT.
>> TIME WITH THE KIDS AND JOEL.
>> Gretchen: AFTER DOING SO MANY
OF THESE STORIES MYSELF, I'M
ALSO AN ORGAN DONOR ON MY
DRIVER'S LICENSE.
IT'S SO IMPORTANT AND WE'RE SO
GLAD THAT YOU ARE HERE WITH THUS
CHRISTMAS AND SHARED THIS
WONDERFUL MIRACLE STORY WITH US.
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
HAVE A WONDERFUL TIME WITH YOUR
FAMILY.
>> MERRY CHRISTMAS.
>> Gretchen: WE NEED MORE
STORIES LIKE THAT, RIGHT?
SPEAKER OF THE HOUSE JOHN
BOEHNER AGREED TO SOME TAX HIKES
IN ORDER TO AVOID THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
BUT NOW THE PRESIDENT HAS
ANOTHER REQUEST.
SO WILL REPUBLICANS BUY INTO
THIS?
WHERE ARE WE IN THE STATE OF
THINGS IN WASHINGTON?
THEN A KID DISRESPECTED HIS
TEACHER.
BUT IT'S NOT THE SCHOOL WHO
PUNISHED HIM.
IT WAS HIS MOM.
HOW SHE TOOK MATTERS INTO HER
OWN HANDS FOR EVERYONE TO SEE
[ Male Announcer ]
IN BLIND TASTE TESTS,
EVEN RAGU USERS CHOSE PREGO.
PREGO?!
BUT I'VE BOUGHT RAGU FOR YEARS.
[ Thinking ] WONDER WHAT OTHER
QUESTIONABLE CHOICES I'VE MADE?
I CHOOSE DATE NUMBER 2!
WHOOO!
[ sigh of relief ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHOOSE TASTE. CHOOSE PREGO.
NESPRESSO.
WHERE I NEVER HAVE TO COMPROMISE
ON ANYTHING.
♪
WHERE JUST ONE TOUCH
CREATES THE PERFECT COFFEE.
WHERE EVERY CAPPUCCINO AND LATTE
IS ONLY MADE WITH FRESH MILK.
AND WHERE THE STAFF
IS EXCEPTIONALLY FRIENDLY.
♪
NESPRESSO. WHAT ELSE?
ADT CAN HELP YOU
TURN ON A FEW LIGHTS.
ACCESS CAMERAS FROM ANYWHERE
TO HELP YOU KEEP AN EYE
ON THINGS.
EVEN BRING FAMILY IN
FROM THE COLD
WHEN YOU'RE NOT THERE.
NOW GET THE ADVANCED TECHNOLOGY
OF ADT
STARTING AT JUST $99
AND SAVE $300.
WITH ADT, YOU GET 24/7
FAST RESPONSE MONITORING
THAT HELPS PROTECT YOU
FROM BURGLARY, FIRE,
AND HIGH LEVELS
OF CARBON MONOXIDE.
PLUS REMOTE ACCESS
TO YOUR HOME.
EVEN CONTROL YOUR THERMOSTAT
TO HELP SAVE ENERGY AND MONEY.
GET ADT INSTALLED
STARTING AT JUST $99.
THAT'S A $300 SAVINGS.
YOU MAY EVEN SAVE UP TO 20%
ON YOUR HOMEOWNERS INSURANCE.
FOR EVERYTHING
THAT MATTERS MOST.
ADT. ALWAYS THERE.
>> WHAT IS BEING CALLED A
STUNNING LITERARY FIND, A DANISH
HISTORIAN DISCOVERED THE LAST
REMAINING UNPUBLISHED FAIRY TALE
OF HANS CHRISTIAN ANDERSEN
CALLED CONGRESS SOLVES THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
[ LAUGHTER ]
IT'S CONSIDERED THE BIGGEST
FAIRY TALE EVER TOLD.
>> Brian: BELIEVE IT OR NOT, WE
ARE GETTING CLOSE TO AT LEAST AN
AGREEMENT.
I DON'T KNOW IF EITHER SIDE IS
GOING TO SUPPORT THE AGREEMENT,
BUT THE LEADERS, PRESIDENT OBAMA
AND SPEAKER BOEHNER, THREE TIMES
MEETING IN THE LAST FIVE DAYS?
>> Gretchen: I STILL THINK IT'S
A FAIRY TALE BECAUSE IT'S JUST A
SHORT-TERM SOLUTION.
EVEN IF THEY COME TO AN
AGREEMENT, IT'S KIND OF A FAIRY
TALE SOLUTION BECAUSE IT DOESN'T
ADDRESS THE PROBLEMS THAT WE'RE
FACING.
>> Brian: NOT IN A MAJOR WAY,
BUT IT DOES ANSWER THE PROBLEMS
THAT HAVE TO BE ANSWERED TO GET
TO THE BUDGET OF THIS UPCOMING
YEAR.
>> Steve: YEP.
LET'S GO DOWN TO WASHINGTON, D.C
KELLY WRIGHT JOINS US LIVE WITH
THE VERY LATEST ON WHAT WE KNOW
REGARDING THE CLIFF.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
>> GOOD MORNING TO YOU ALL.
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER MET
WITH PRESIDENT OBAMA AT THE
WHITE HOUSE ON MONDAY OF THE IT
LASTED ABOUT 45 MINUTES.
MR. BOEHNER PUT THE REPUBLICAN
DEAL BEFORE THE PRESIDENT,
OFFERING A TO CUT TAXES OR LET
TAX CUTS EXPIRE FOR THOSE
EARNING MORE THAN A MILLION
DOLLARS A YEAR.
THAT'S A MAJOR CONCESSION FOR
MR. BOEHNER AND A COUNTEROFFER
THE PRESIDENT SOFTENED HIS
DEMAND FOR TAX HIKE WHEN THOSE
EARNING MORE THAN $250,000 A
YEAR BY RAISING IT TO $400,000 A
YEAR.
>> IN ORDER TO ACHIEVE A BROAD
DEFICIT REDUCTION PACKAGE THAT
PUTS OUR ECONOMY ON A
SUSTAINABLE FISCAL PATH IN THE
FUTURE, A CERTAIN LEVEL OF
REVENUE GLEANED FROM THE WEALTHY
HAS TO BE MET.
>> SO A ROUGH OUTLINE OF THE
PROPOSED DEAL ESSENTIALLY CALLS
FOR $1 TRILLION IN CUTS,
$1 TRILLION IN REVENUE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS ALSO GIVING
IN TO SOME OF THE GOP'S DEMANDS
FOR SPENDING CUTS ON ENTITLEMENT
PROGRAMS SUCH AS LOWERING COSTS
OF LIVING INCREASES FOR PEOPLE
ON SOCIAL SECURITY.
NOW, THE CONCESSIONS FROM BOTH
SIDES SHOW THEY COULD BE CLOSE
TO A DEAL.
IN A STATEMENT, BOEHNER'S
SPOKESMAN SAID THEY ARE MAKING A
STEP IN THE RIGHT DIRECTION,
ADDING, WE HOPE TO CONTINUE
DISCUSSIONS WITH THE PRESIDENT
SO WE CAN REACH AN AGREEMENT
THAT IS TRULY BALANCED AND
BEGINS TO SOLVE OUR SPENDING
PROBLEM.
AND TIME, OF COURSE, IS OF THE
ESSENCE.
CONGRESS HAS TWO WEEKS TO HAMMER
OUT A DEAL BEFORE AUTOMATIC CUTS
GO INTO EFFECT ON JANUARY 1.
THOSE SPENDING CUTS WOULD BE
DEEP IN DEFENSE AND DOMESTIC
PROGRAMS, PLUS TAX HIKES WOULD
HURT AND HIT NEARLY ALL WAGE
EARNERS.
ECONOMISTS AND BUSINESS LEADERS
WARN IT COULD THROW THE ECONOMY
INTO ANOTHER RECESSION IF
SOMETHING ISN'T DONE.
BY THE WAY, HARRY REID SAID IT
APPEARS THE SENATE MAY BE COMING
BACK THE DAY AFTER CHRISTMAS TO
DEAL WITH THIS.
>> Gretchen: YEAH.
I SAW THAT.
>> Steve: ALL RIGHT.
KELLY WRIGHT, WE THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
LET ME GET THIS STRAIGHT.
THEY'RE TALKING ABOUT RAISING
TAXES A TRILLION DOLLARS AND
TALKING ABOUT CUTTING TAXES A
TRILLION DOLLARS.
THAT'S A WASH.
>> Gretchen: EXACTLY.
>> Steve: WHY DON'T THEY STOP
SPENDING AS MUCH MONEY?
>> Gretchen: WHICH IS MY POINT
THAT, THE FAIRY TALE OR THE
NIGHTMARE CONTINUES IN
WASHINGTON.
>> Brian: THE PRESIDENT STILL
WANTS HIS STIMULUS MONEY BUILT
IN.
>> Steve: HE DOES.
80 BILLION.
PLUS, THE OTHER THING ABOUT THIS
PARTICULAR FISCAL CLIFF AS
DETAILED IN THE "WASHINGTON
POST" AND ELSEWHERE THIS
MORNING, IS THAT THE REPUBLICANS
WOULD GIVE THE PRESIDENT TWO
YEARS WORTH OF DEBT LIMIT.
REMEMBER THE PRESIDENT WANTED
UNLIMITED FOREVER, ANY TIME YOU
NEED MORE MONEY, HE COULD JACK
IT UP HIMSELF.
THE REPUBLICANS WOULD GIVE HIM
TWO YEARS.
EVERYBODY THOUGHT THE
REPUBLICANS' ACE IN THE HOLE
WOULD BE THE DEBT LIMIT FIGHT.
>> Gretchen: IT'S CALLED YOUR
LEVERAGE.
SAYING BYE-BYE TO IT.
>> Brian: THEY GET THE BUSH TAX
CUTS PERMANENT FOR EVERYONE WHO
MAKES NOW UNDER $400,000 IF THE
REPORTS ARE CORRECT.
>> Gretchen: LET'S TALK ABOUT
OTHER STORIES MAKING HEADLINES.
HE WILL BE THE FIRST
AFRICAN-AMERICAN SENATOR EVER IN
SOUTH CAROLINA.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT REPUBLICAN
CONGRESSMAN TIM SCOTT.
THE GOVERNOR OF SOUTH CAROLINA,
NIKKI HALEY, PICKED HIM TO
REPLACE JIM DEMINT.
HE PROMISE TO DO FOCUS ON OUR
DEBT CRISIS, WHAT WE WERE JUST
TALKING ABOUT.
>> WE FACE IN AMERICA IS NO
MATTER WHAT WE DO TO INCREASE
TAXES, IT'S SIMPLY WILL NOT HAVE
A DENT IN OUR ANNUAL DEFICIT,
MUCH LESS THE 16 TRILLION PLUS
DOLLARS IN OUR NATIONAL DEBT.
SO FOR TO US CLOSE THE GAP,
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO HAVE A
SERIOUS CONVERSATION ABOUT
SPENDING REFORM, BALANCED BUDGET
AMENDMENT.
>> Gretchen: SO SCOTT WILL BE
THE FIRST AFRICAN-AMERICAN
SENATOR THE SOUTH HAS SEEN SINCE
RECONSTRUCTION.
>> Brian: TERRIFYING NIGHT FOR
TWO PARENTS IN WASHINGTON WHEN
STRONG WINDS SENT A HUGE TREE
CRASHING THROUGH THEIR HOME,
LANDING INCHES FROM THEIR
SLEEPING BABY.
>> COME DOWNSTAIRS, SEE A TREE
FALL INTO THE NEIGHBOR'S YARD,
HIT THEIR YARD.
IT'S THE BABY'S ROOM.
>> THERE IS A COUPLE BROKEN
TRUSSES, SHEETING HANGING DOWN.
SO YEAH, I'M SURE IT WAS SCARY
FOR THE PARENTS.
>> Brian: WOW, THE TREE LANDED A
COUPLE FEET FROM THE CRIB.
LUCKILY THE KID DID NOT GET A
SCRATCH.
>> Steve: TURNS OUT ONE KEY TO
FIGHTING CANCER HAS BEEN IN OUR
REFRIGERATORS ALL ALONG IN A
PRODUCE DRAWER.
CHILDREN, IT'S BROCCOLI.
RESEARCHERS SAY BROCCOLI
CONTAINS A COMPOUND THAT KILLS
CANCEROUS CELLS WHILE LEAVING
HEALTHY CELLS INTACT.
THEY HOPE THOSE CELLS CAN BE
DEVELOPD INTO A NEW MEDICINE FOR
CHILDREN WITH LEUKEMIA WHOSE
BODIES DON'T RESPOND TO THE
TYPICAL TREATMENT.
I GOT FEELING BROCCOLI SALES A
GOING TO SOAR TODAY.
>> Brian: SORRY GEORGE BUSH, 41.
>> Gretchen: MY PEDIATRICIAN
TOLD ME THE ONE VEGETABLE TO
HAVE KIDS EAT, BROCCOLI.
>>> A STUNT GETTING A PUBLIC
PUNISHMENT AFTER HE CURSED AT
HIS TEACHER.
HIS MOTHER MADE HIM WEAR SIGN
FOR THREE DAYS.
IT READS, I DISRESPECTED MY
TEACHER.
I WOULD LIKE TO APOLOGIZE TO HER
AND ALL ADULTS.
>> HE HAS A YOUNGER SISTER AND
BROTHER THAT LOOK UP TO HIM.
HE NEEDS TO BE A ROLE MODEL.
IF THIS IS WHAT IT TARRANT
COUNTY THEN THIS IS WHAT IT
TAKES.
>> Gretchen: I LIKE THAT MOM.
SHE HOPES THIS WILL TEACH HER
12-YEAR-OLD A LESSON HE'LL NEVER
FORGET.
>> Steve: MEANWHILE, THIS
MORNING THERE ARE JUST TWO WORLD
WAR II VETERANS SURVIVING IN THE
U.S. SENATE.
THAT AFTER THE PASSING OF
NINE-TERM HAWAIIAN SENATOR
DANIEL INOUYE.
ONE STORY IN HIS LIFE, WHICH
BRET BAIER DETAILS RIGHT HERE.
>> DANIEL INOUYE REPRESENTED
HAWAII IN CONGRESS FROM THE TIME
IT BECAME A STATE IN 1959.
HE WAS INITIALLY ELECTED AS THE
STATE'S FIRST HOUSE MEMBER FOR
TWO TERMS.
SUBSEQUENTLY AS SENATOR FOR NINE
TERMS.
BUT HIS STORIED TENURE BEGAN AS
A FRESHMAN HOUSE MEMBER, BY THE
END OF HIS CAREER, HE WAS THE
MOST SENIOR MEMBER, OR PRESIDENT
PRO TEM, MAKING HIM THIRD RADIO
INN LINE FOR THE PRESIDENCY.
HE PREFERRED A REVERENCE FOR THE
INSTITUTION OVER THE
PARTISANSHIP DISPLAYED BY MANY
COLLEAGUES.
ALTHOUGH HE RARELY APPEARED AT
CONFERENCES OR MADE SPEECHES, HE
HAD AN UNDENIABLY COMMANDING
PRESENCE.
HIS WORDS TENDED TO CARRY WEIGHT
WHEN HE DID SPEAK OUT ON ISSUES.
HE CHAIRED FOUR DIFFERENT
COMMITTEES DURING HIS SENATE
TENURE.
THE INTELLIGENCE COMMITTEE, THE
INIAN AFFAIRS COMMITTEE,
COMMERCE COMMITTEE, AND THE
APPROPRIATIONS COMMITTEE.
HE ASSUMED THE HELM OF THAT
PANEL AFTER THE LEGENDARY
SENATOR ROBERT BIRD FROM WEST
VIRGINIA RELINK WINKED THE --
RELINQUISHED THE GAVEL.
HE WAS A WITNESS TO THE PEARL
HARBOR ATTACK AND THE FIRST
JAPANESE AMERICAN TO SERVE IN
EITHER CHAMBER OF CONGRESS.
HE ALSO HAD THE DISTINCTION OF
SERVING IN THE 442 REGIMENTAL
COMBAT TEAM, A SEGREGATED UNIT
OF JAPANESE AMERICANS DURING
WORLD WAR II, THE MOST DECORATED
UNIT IN AMERICAN HISTORY.
>> THE BOMBING OF PEARL HARBOR,
70 YEARS AGO, BEGAN A PERIOD OF
MY LIFE WHEN I BECAME AN ADULT
AND I HOPE A GOOD AMERICAN.
>> THE THEN WAR DEPARTMENT HAD
INITIALLY DETERMINED THAT THE
SECOND GENERATION AIL YELLS WERE
PROHIBITED FROM SERVING IN THE
MILITARY.
>> NONE OF THEM HAD COMMITTED
ANY CRIME.
INVESTIGATION AFTER
INVESTIGATION DISCLOSED THAT.
NO SABOTAGE, NO ESPIONAGE, NO
ASSAULT, NOTHING.
BUT THEY WERE ROUNDED UP AND
PLACED INTO THESE CAMPS.
>> AFTER INOUYE AND OTHER
FELLOWS SUCCESSFULLY PETITIONED
THE ROOSEVELT ADMINISTRATION TO
CHANGE ITS POLICY, THE MILITARY
BEGAN TO ACCEPT THEM FOR SERVICE
ON A SEPARATED BASIS.
>> PRESIDENT ROOSEVELT ISSUED A
STATEMENT SAYING AMERICANISM IS
NOT A MATTER OF BLOOD OR COLOR.
AMERICANISM IS A MATTER OF HEART
AND SOUL.
>> HE WAS PROMOTE TO DO A
SERGEANT WITHIN HIS FIRST YEAR
AND EVENTUALLY BECAME A PLATOON
LEADER WHILE FIGHTING NAZI
FORCES IN TUSCANY.
HE SUFFERED MULTIPLE INJURIES
AND LATER HAD HIS ARM AMPUTATED.
AFTER THE WAR, HE EARNED A TOTAL
OF 16 MEDALS AND CITATIONS FOR
HIS SERVICE, INCLUDING THE
DISTINGUISHED SERVICE CROSS, THE
BRONZE STAR, THE PURPLE HEART,
AND THE MEDAL OF HONOR.
BUT HE WASN'T AWARDED THE LAST
RECOGNITION UNTIL 2000.
NONE OF THE SOLDIERS OF THE
442nd REGIMENT EVER RECEIVED
THE MEDAL OF HONOR.
THE MILITARY'S HIGHEST
DECORATION MORE THAN 50 YEARS
LATER, DISTINGUISHED SERVICE
CROSSES GIVEN TO INOUYE AND 21
OTHER MEMBERS OF THE REGIMENT
WERE UPGRADED TO THE MEDAL OF
HONOR.
INOUYE WAS IN THE SPOTLIGHT
DURING THE 1970S AS A MEMBER OF
THE WATERGATE COMMITTEE PROBING
THE ALLEGED CRIMINAL ACTIVITIES
OF THE NIXON ADMINISTRATION.
>> WOULD YOU CARE TO RECOMMEND
TO THIS COMMITTEE ANY
LEGISLATION TO PREVENT THE
RECURRENCE OF SOME OF THE
IRREGULARITIES  THAT OCCURRED IN
THE 1972 PRESIDENTIAL ELECTION?
>> IN 1987, ECHARD ANOTHER
CONGRESSIONAL PANEL
INVESTIGATING EXECUTIVE BRANCH
WRONGDOING.
IRAN-CONTRA COMMITTEE.
>> WE'LL MISS HIM.
>> HE LIVED A REMARKABLE
AMERICAN LIFE FILLED WITH
DIGNITY AND GRACE OF THE TRUE
HERO THAT HE WAS.
>> DANIEL INOUYE WAS 88.
IN WASHINGTON, BRET BAIER, FOX
NEWS.
>> Steve: THANK YOU.
THERE IS A STORY OUT THERE THIS
MORNING THAT SENATOR INOUYE'S
FINAL WORD, ALOHA.
>> Gretchen: THAT'S VERY FITTING
COMING FROM THE STATE OF HAWAII.
COMING UP ON "FOX & FRIENDS,"
PRESIDENTS AND THEIR PETS, HOW
GEORGE H.W. BUSH'S LITTLE DOG
CAUSED SO MUCH DRAMA AT THE
WHITE HOUSE AND OTHER INSIDER
STORIES THAT YOU WON'T HEAR
ANYWHERE ELSE.
>> Brian: STILL NEED EXTRA CASH?
CHERYL CASONE HAS -- SHE'S GOT
FIVE COMPANIES LOOKING FOR
SEASONAL HELP RIGHT NOW.
SHE'S WALKING THIS WAY.
HAVE A GOOD NIGHT.
RE YOU GO. YOU, TOO.
I'M GOING TO DREAM
ABOUT THAT STEAK.
ABOUT THAT TIRAMISU.
WHAT A NIGHT, HUH?
BUT, UM, CAN THE TEST DRIVE
BE OVER NOW?
HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A PASSAT.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN, $0 DUE AT SIGNING,
$0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME R CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
I just finished a bowl of your
new Light Chicken Pot Pie Soup
and it's so rich
and creamy...
is it really 100 calories?
Let me put you on webcan...
...lean roasted chicken...
and a creamy broth
Mmm
I can still see you.
[ Male announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
YOU KNOW, FROM OUR 4,000
TELEVISION COMMERCIALS.
YEP, THERE I AM WITH FLO.
HOO-HOO! WATCH IT!
[Chuckles] ANYHOO, 3 MILLION
PEOPLE SWITCHED TO ME LAST YEAR,
SAVING AN AVERAGE
OF $475.
[Sigh] IT FEELS GOOD
TO HELP PEOPLE SAVE...
WITH GREAT DISCOUNTS LIKE
SAFE DRIVER, MULTICAR,
AND MULTIPOLICY.
SO CALL ME TODAY.
YOU'LL BE GLAD YOU DID.
CANNONBOX!
[SPLASH!]
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>> Steve: ALL RIGHT.
WELCOME BACK.
QUICK HEADLINES.
CELEBRITY HACKER CHRISTOPHER
CHANEY WILL GET TEN YEARS HYPED
BARS FOR POSTING CELEBRITY
PICTURES ON-LINE.
TROPICANA IS TRYING TO WIN OVER
MOMS TRYING TO CUT DOWN ON SUGAR
WITH VEGETABLE JUICE.
THE NEW JUICE CALLED FARM STAND
IS GOING TO CONTAIN CARROTS AND
BEETS AND OTHER MIXED
VEGETABLES, COMING TO A GROCERY
AISLE NEAR YOU.
>> Brian: SOUNDS GOOD.
>> Steve: IT DOES.
>> Brian: ALL RIGHT.
SEASONAL POSITIONS AREN'T JUST
FORT HOLIDAYS.
COMPANIES STILL LOOKING FOR
SEASONAL SPOTS BASED ON THEIR
BUSY TIMES.
HERE WITH THE TOP FIVE COMPANIES
HIRING IS CHERYL CASONE.
LET'S CONTINUE YOUR STREAK OF
GETTING PEOPLE JOBS.
>> YEAH.
WE'VE BEEN SUCCESSFUL.
>> Brian: LET'S TALK WEDDINGS.
>> 25% OF ENGAGEMENTS HAPPEN
BETWEEN THANKSGIVING AND NEW
YEAR'S.
DAVID'S BRIDAL IS HIRING NOW,
BUT THEY'LL NEED THIS FOR THE
SPRING.
HELP FOR THE SPRING.
THEY'VE GOT 3,000 SEASONAL
CONSULTANT JOBS AVAILABLE.
YOU MAKE 7.5 AN HOUR BURKS ADD
COMMISSION INTO THAT, DEPENDING
ON WHAT YOU SELL.
THEY NEED PEOPLE -- THEY'D LIKE
TO GET EVERYBODY HIRED BY THE
FIRST WEEK OF JANUARY.
SO GO NOW.
THAT JOB WITH GO INTO MARCH AND
APRIL.
>> Brian: NESTLE TOLL HOUSE
CAFE.
>> IS A COMPANY THAT HAS A
PARTNERSHIP WITH NESTLE.
IT'S NOT TO BE CONFUSED WITH THE
CORPORATE COMPANY.
YOU MAKE ABOUT 8 TO SO AN HOUR.
YOU CAN BE A SAMPLER FOR THE
SANTA EXPERIENCE.
OR YOU CAN BE A CAKE DECORATOR.
THEY'VE 400 JOBS HIRING THROUGH
THE SEASON.
IF YOU WANT THIS KIND OF JOB, GO
TODAY.
GO TODAY, GO TOMORROW.
IT MAY ONLY BE FOR A COUPLE
THREE WEEKS, FOUR WEEKS,
WHATEVER, BUT IF THEY'RE REALLY,
REALLY BUSY, THEY'RE GOING TO
TAKE NEW AND START YOU.
>> Brian: THIS DEFIES WHAT
SEASONAL HELP IS.
SEASONAL TAX.
>> THAT WILL BE BIG.
I DON'T THINK WE'LL BE ABLE TO
'CAUSE WE'RE NOT GOING TO KNOW
WHAT OUR TAX STRUCTURES ARE
GOING TO BE.
THIRD LARGEST TAX COMPANY
THROUGHOUT THE COUNTRY RIGHT
NOW, THEY'RE GROWING.
THEY NEED ABOUT 50,000 SEASONAL
WORKERS.
AGAIN, THIS IS THROUGH TAX
SEASON.
THIS IS GOING INTO THE SPRING.
10 TO 12 BUCKS PER HOUR, 5%
BONUS OF ALL THE REVENUE THAT
YOU BOOK.
POSITION BEGIN JANUARY 1.
GOING TO BE GOING THROUGHOUT THE
TAX SEASON.
>> Brian: THIS IS SECOND TIME AT
LEAST I REMEMBER THE BOSTON
MARKET BEING UP THERE.
>> YEAH.
BOSTON MARKET, AGAIN, ONE OF
THOSE COMPANIES THAT'S REALLY
BEEN HIRING.
THEY'RE KIND OF LIKE CHIPOTLE.
2,000 PEOPLE FOR THE HOLIDAYS,
DRIVERS, CASHIERS, PEOPLE THAT
CAN HELP SERVE, PREP, COOK.
BUT A LOT OF THESE JOBS WILL GO
THROUGH THE HOLIDAY SEASON AS
WELL INTO NEXT YEAR.
>> Brian: WHAT ARE LIMITED
BRANDS?
>> YOU ACTUALLY DO KNOW, THEY
OWN VICTORIA SECRET.
RING A BELL?
>> Brian: REALLY?
>> YOUR FAVORITE COMPANY EVER.
THEY ALSO OWN WHITE BARN AND
CANDLE AND BATH AND BODY WORKS.
55,000 EMPLOYEES FOR THE HOLIDAY
SEASON.
THEY HIRED THE SAME AMOUNT THIS
YEAR AS LAST YEAR.
THEY STILL NEED HELP.
A LOT OF LINGERIE TO BE SOLD.
>> Brian: GO GET A JOB AND WRITE
YOU.
>> YES.
THE GUEST YOU HAD ON YESTERDAY,
SHE GOT A JOB AND WROTE US.
SO IF YOU GET A JOB THROUGH THE
SITE, E-MAIL US OR IF YOU'RE A
COMPANY LOOKING TO HIRE, E-MAIL
US.
YOU MAY BE ON TV ONE WAY OR THE
OTHER OF THE I'LL PUT ALL THE
DETAILS ON MY WEB SITE.
>> Brian: THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
COMING UP, TAKE A GOOD LOOK AT
THIS PICTURE.
DO THESE LOOK LIKE SPIES TO YOU?
FORMER PRESIDENT'S DOGS
SUSPECTED OF WORKING FOR THE
SOVIET AS SOON AS ON THIS DAY IN
1974, HARRY CHAPIN HAD THE
NUMBER ONE SONG "CATS IN THE
CRADLE."
IT TAKES NINE HOURS TO SING
BURKS IT'S GOOD.
♪ WHEN YOU COMING HOME DAD
♪ I DON'T KNOW WHEN
♪ BUT WE'LL GET TOGETHER THEN
♪ YOU KNOW WE'LL HAVE A GOOD
TIME THEN ♪
♪
BEGIN.
TOMATO,
OBVIOUSLY.
HAHA. THERE'S MORE
THAN THAT THOUGH,
THERE'S A KICK TO IT.
WAHLALALALALLALA!
SMOOTH, BUT CRISP.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE DRINKING
A FOOD THAT'S A DRINK,
OR A DRINK THAT'S A FOOD,
WOOOOOH!
[ Male Announcer ] TASTE IT
AND DESCRIBE THE INDESCRIBABLE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
[ coughs ]
[ baby crying ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
ROBITUSSIN® LIQUID FORMULA
SOOTHES YOUR THROAT ON CONTACT
AND THE ACTIVE INGREDIENT
RELIEVES YOUR COUGH.
ROBITUSSIN®. DON'T SUFFER
THE COUGHEQUENCES™.
>> Gretchen: FROM PUPPIES AND
PONYIES AT 1600 PENNSYLVANIA
AVENUE.
>> Steve: SOMEBODY IS HORSING
AROUND.
WHETHER THEY WERE PROVIDING
EXXONIANSHIP OR SOFTENING THE
PRESIDENTIAL IMAGE, THE PETS
PLAYED AN IMPORTANT ROLE IN
WHITE HOUSE HISTORY.
>> Brian: YEP.
JENNIFER IS THE AUTHOR OF "PETS
AT THE WHITE HOUSE, 50 YEARS OF
PRESIDENTS AND THEIR PETS."
WELCOME.
>> THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
>> Brian: WHERE DID THIS IDEA
COME FROM?
>> I WAS SPOILED GROWING UP AND
SO MY PARENTS REALLY INDULGED US
WITH SO MANY PETS.
I HAD ANOTHER BOOK I WROTE
"CHRISTMAS AT THE WHITE HOUSE,"
THE FIRST BOOK WRITTEN ABOUT
CHRISTMAS AT 1600 PENNSYLVANIA,
INSPIRED BY MY MOM AND ALL HER
WONDERFUL CHRISTMAS TREES SHE
PUT UP EVERY YEAR.
WE WERE WORKING ON A CHRISTMAS
BOOK AND KEPT COMING ACROSS ALL
THESE FABULOUS IMAGES.
>> Steve: LET'S START WITH THE
KENNEDYS.
THEY WOUND UP WITH A DID YOU GO
WHICH WAS A GIFT FROM RUSSIA
WHICH WAS A PROBLEM BECAUSE WE
WERE IN A COLD WAR.
>> EXACTLY.
>> Steve: WHERE DID HE WIND UP
GOING?
>> WHEN SHE ARRIVED, SHE WAS THE
DAUGHTER OF THE FAMOUS SPACE
DOG.
BEFORE CAROLINE COULD TAKE HER
HOME, SHE HAD TO GO TO WALTER
REED MEDICAL FACILITY TO MAKE
SURE SHE DIDN'T HAVE BOMBS,
GERMS OR LISTENING DEVICES.
>> Gretchen: WOW.
>> YEAH.
>> Gretchen: KENNEDYS AND THE
PONIES?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
MACARONI, EVERY LITTLE GIRL
WANTED A PONY AFTER SEEING
CAROLINE KENNEDY WITH MACARONI.
SHE ACTUALLY RECEIVED HER OWN
FAN MAIL WHILE AT THE WHITE
HOUSE.
>> Gretchen: WOW.
TODAY SHE WOULD HAVE A TWITTER
ACCOUNT.
PRESIDENT FORD AND LIBERTY.
>> MY FAVORITE IS LIBERTY WHEN
SHE WAS EXPECTING NINE PUPPIES,
WOKE UP PRESIDENT FORD AT
9:00 A.M. TO GO OUT.
SO PRESIDENT FORD FOUND HIS BATH
ROBE AND SLIPPERS, TOOK HER OUT
TO THE SOUTH LAWN.
SHE DID HER BUSINESS, THEY
TURNED AROUND TO COME IN AND
THEY WERE LOCKED OUT OF THE
WHITE HOUSE AT 3 A.M
THEY HAD TO GO UP THREE STORIES,
STILL ALL THE WAY LOCKED OUT.
HAD TO GO BACK DOWNSTAIRS BEFORE
THE SECRET SERVICE REALIZED THE
PRESIDENT WAS --
>> Brian: TRUMAN DIDN'T HAVE A
BALCONY.
WHAT ABOUT PRESIDENT REAGAN?
>> PRESIDENT REAGAN HAD TWO
DOGS, LUCK ENTRY REX.
THEY WERE FABULOUS.
LUCKY WAS DAUNTING.
SO SHE WENT TO LIVE AT THE
WESTERN WHITE HOUSE WHERE SHE
COULD RUN FREE AND HAVE MORE
FUN.
>> Steve: LET'S TALK ABOUT 41'S
RANGER.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
RANGER AND MILLIE, THERE IS NO
GREATER --
>> Steve: SHE WROTE A BOOK!
>> SHE DID.
MILLIE, SHE WAS THE ONLY TRULY
PRESIDENTIAL DOG.
SHE WAS PRESIDENTIAL TO THE
CORE.
SHE NEVER BARKED AND WALKED
PERFECTLY WITH MRS. BUSH.
>> Gretchen: BARNEY, THE NEXT
DOG WAS THE FIRST ONE TO HAVE
THE CAMERA.
WE GOT TO WRAP IT UP.
CHECK OUT THIS BEAUTIFUL BOOK
FOR CHRISTMAS.
THANKS SO MUCH.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> Brian: I'M GLAD YOU GREW UP
SPOILED.
>> Steve: COMING UP, THE GUNS
USED IN NEWTOWN WERE PURCHASED
LEGALLY.
SO IS A WEAPONS BAN THE ANSWER?
LAURA INGRAHAM WEIGHS IN JUST A
COUPLE MINUTES FROM RIGHT NOW.
♪
[ engine revs ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THE MERCEDES-BENZ WINTER EVENT
IS BACK,
WITH THE PERFECT VEHICLE
THAT'S JUST RIGHT FOR YOU,
NO MATTER WHICH LIST YOU'RE ON.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
C250 FOR $349 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
YOU HAVE A PLAN?
FIRST WE'RE GONNA
CHECK OUR BAGS FOR FREE,
THANKS
TO OUR EXPLORER CARD.
THEN, THE UNITED CLUB.
MY MOTR
WAS SO WRONG ABOUT YOU.
NEXT,
WE GET PRIORY BOARDING
ON OUR FLIGHT
I BOOKED WITH MILES.
ALL BECAUSE OF THE CARD.
AND ME.
OKAY, WHAT'S THE PLAN?
PLAN?
MM-HMM.
WE'RE ON VACATION.
THERE IS NO PLAN.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ] THE UNITED
MILEAGEPLUS EXPLORER CARD.
THE MILEAGE CARD
WITH SPECI PERKS ON UNITED.
GET IT AND YOU'RE IN.
>> Gretchen: GOOD MORNING,
EVERYBODY.
TODAY IS TUESDAY, DECEMBER 18,
2012.
I'M GRETCHEN CARLSON.
THANKS FOR SHARING YOUR TIME
WITH US TODAY.
FOUR DAYS NOW SINCE THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING THAT SHOOK OUR NATION
TO ITS CORE.
SOME STUDENTS HEADING BACK TO
CLASS, BUT COUNTLESS QUESTIONS
REMAIN.
WE'RE LIVE ON THE SCENE WITH
SOME HERO STORIES FROM
CONNECTICUT.
>> Steve: THE GUNS USED IN THAT
NEWTOWN SCHOOL MASSACRE WERE
PURCHASED LEGALLY.
SO WOULD A SIMPLE WEAPONS BAN
STOP IT FROM HAPPENING AGAIN?
WE'RE GOING TO TALK TO LAURA
INGRAHAM LIVE IN DC IN MOMENTS.
>> Brian: WE'RE GETTING OUR
FIRST LOOK AT THE U.S. MARINE
LOCKED UP IN MEXICO.
HE'S CHAINED TO A BED.
MEXICO SAID THAT'S GOOD
TREATMENT.
HIS MOTHER JOINS US WITH HER
REACTION AND WHAT SHE PLANS TO
DO NEXT.
"FOX & FRIENDS" STARTS NOW.
>> Gretchen: GOOD MORNING,
EVERYBODY.
WE'RE GOING TO CONTINUE OUR
COVERAGE NOW OF THE SITUATION IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT OF THE
THERE IS SOME HERO STORIES, GOOD
NEWS STORIES COMING OUT OF THIS
AS WELL.
IN THE MEANTIME, UNFORTUNATELY,
WE'RE SAYING GOOD-BYE TO SOME OF
THESE YOUNG CHILDREN.
TWO MORE VICTIMS ARE LAID TO
REST.
ONE FOR SIX-YEAR-OLD JAMES
MATTIOLI, NICKNAMED JAY.
YOU SEE HIM WITH HIS PUMPKIN
FROM HALLOWEEN.
HIS FAMILY SAYS HE LOVED RECESS,
WHAT BOY DOESN'T?
HE ALSO LOVED MATH, THEY CALLED
HIM THEIR NUMBERS GUY.
THE OTHER IS FOR SIX-YEAR-OLD
JESSICA RICOS WHO LOVED
EVERYTHING ABOUT HORSES AND
PLAYING WITH HER LITTLE
BROTHERS.
AS THE COMMUNITY MOURNS STUDENTS
AT OTHER NEWTOWN SCHOOLS ARE
HEADING BACK TO CLASS FOR THE
FIRST TIME AS POLICE LEARN MORE
ABOUT WHAT MAY HAVE LED TO THIS
HORRIBLE SHOOTING.
PETER DOOCY JOINS US NOW LIVE
WITH WHAT HE'S LEARNED.
GOOD MORNING, PETER.
>> GOOD MORNING, GRETCHEN.
WE'RE LEARNING MORE NOW ABOUT
THE EXACT MOMENT THE PARENTS OF
AT LEAST 18 YOUNG VICTIM HIGH
SCHOOL THEIR HEARTS BROKEN ON
FRIDAY.
IT HAPPENED ABOUT FIVE HOURS
AFTER THE SHOOTING IN THE
FIREHOUSE NOT TOO FAR AWAY FROM
THE SCHOOL WHEN THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT CAME IN AND TOLD
THOSE PARENTS THAT IF THEIR
FIRST GRADER HADN'T YET EMERGED
FROM THE SCHOOL ALIVE, THEY
NEVER WOULD.
>> IT WAS EVIDENT TO ME THAT
THERE WAS A RELUCTANCE TO TELL
PARENTS AND LOVED ONES IN THAT E
PERSON THEY WERE WAITING FOR WAS
NOT GOING TO RETURN AND THAT HAD
GONEN FOR A PERIOD OF TIME.
I MADE THE DECISION THAT -- TO
HAVE THAT GO ON ANY LONGER WAS
WRONG OF THE I DID IT.
>> AUTHORITIES SAY BEFORE
FRIDAY, THEY NEVER HAD ANY
CONTACT WITH MASS MURDERER ADAM
LANZA, BUT THAT TWO ADULT
SURVIVORS OF HIS RAMPAGE ARE
RECOVERING FROM GUNSHOT WOUNDS
TO THEIR LOWER EXTREMITIES.
EACH OF THE HUNDREDS OF ROUNDS
OF AMMUNITION FROM MULTIPLE
CARTRIDGES RECOVERED AT THE
SCENE ARE GOING TO BE ANDED
INDIVIDUALLY AND CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE SAY THEY WILL HAVE
MORE DETAILED INFORMATION FOR US
SOMETIME.
IT JUST MIGHT TAKE A WHILE.
>> I KNOW, WE KNOW AS
INVESTIGATESSORS THAT THE PEOPLE
OF CONNECTICUT, THE PEOPLE OF
THIS TOWN OF NEWTOWN WANT TO
KNOW WHAT HAPPENED, WE'RE GOING
TO DO THAT.
WE'RE GOING TO PROVIDE THEM ANY
INFORMATION AND ALL INFORMATION.
WE'LL PAINT A CRYSTAL CLEAR
PICTURE AS MUCH AS WE POSSIBLY
CAN.
BUT IT IS A SLOW PROCESS.
>> MOVING TRUCKS WITH POLICE
ESCORT TOOK FURNITURE FROM SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL OVER TO
CHALK HILL MIDDLE SCHOOL IN
NEARBY MONROE LAST NIGHT.
THAT'S WHERE THIS PLACE --
DISPLACED STUDENTS WILL
CLASS WHILE OFFICIALS DECIDE IF
THEY EVER WANT TO SEND ANY
STUDENT BACK TO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
BACK TO YOU IN NEW YORK.
>> Steve: THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
BY THE WAY, THE CHIEF MEDICAL
EXAMINER FOR CONNECTICUT SAID
YESTERDAY THAT AS THE FUNERALS
STARTED YESTERDAY, AS OF LAST
NIGHT, NOBODY HAD CLAIMED THE
BODY OF THE SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA,
OR HIS MOTHER.
>> Brian: THE BROTHER AND THE
DAD HAVE BEEN QUESTIONED FOR
HOURS.
>> Steve: LET'S DEAL IN LAURA
INGRAHAM WHO JOINSES FROM OUR
NATION'S CAPITOL.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
>> GOOD TO SEE YOU.
I'M FROM CONNECTICUT, UP THE
ROAD FROM NEWTOWN.
BUT I KNOW THAT TOWN VERY WELL
AND IT'S AN IDYLLIC PLACE WITH
GREAT PEOPLE AND WE'VE SEEN SOME
AMAZING EXAMPLES OF COMPASSION,
KINDNESS AND NEIGHBOR HELPING
NEIGHBOR AND I HOPE THAT OF THE
STORIES THAT YOU'RE TELLING
TODAY, THE MEMORIES OF THESE
YOUNG PEOPLE, WHAT THEY BROUGHT
TO THE COMMUNITY, I HOPE THAT'S
WHAT WE FOCUS ON BECAUSE THAT IS
THE SPIRIT OF THE SEASON AND NOT
THE FREAK THAT COMMITTED THESE
ACTS.
>> Steve: THERE ARE A NUMBER OF
DEMOCRAT LAW MAKERS WHO ALREADY
ARE CALLING FOR STRICTER GUN
CONTROLS.
WE'VE GOT LOTS OF GUN LAWS ON
THE BOOKS RIGHT NOW.
BUT YOU SEE THE STATISTICS AND
IT LOOKS LIKE IN STATES LIKE
CALIFORNIA AND OHIO AND
COLORADO, PEOPLE ARE BUYING
THESE AR 15 RIFLES AS QUICKLY AS
THEY CAN 'CAUSE THEY'RE AFRAID
THE GOVERNMENT WILL STEP IN AND
THEY WON'T BE ABLE TO PROTECT
THEMSELVES.
>> YEAH.
I THINK THIS HAPPENS A LOT.
IT HAPPENED IN THE AFTERMATH OF
THE ELECTION, TOO.
PEOPLE ASSUME THAT WHEN
PRESIDENT OBAMA WAS RELIE
DETECTORRED, THERE WOULD BE SOME
TYPE OF NEW GUN INITIATIVE ON
THE BOOKS.
SO PEOPLE WENT OUT AND BOUGHT
GUNS THEN.
LOOK, I COME FROM A FAMILY OF
PEOPLE WHO WENT HUNTING AND GUN
CLUB MEMBERS AND SO FORTH IN
CONNECTICUT.
MY FAMILY WAS ALWAYS VERY
CAREFUL ABOUT GUN SAFETY AND
THAT'S JUST THE WAY WE WERE
BROUGHT UP.
WE SPENT A LOT OF TIME IN TEXAS.
PEOPLE I KNOW THERE, BIG GUN
OWNERS, BIG INTO GUN SAFETY.
>> Gretchen: WHAT'S THE PROBLEM
HERE IF IT'S NOT -- IS IT THAT
THE LAWS ON THE BOOKS ARE NOT
BEING ENFORCED?
IS IT THAT -- SHOULD THERE BE
ANY LIMIT ON SOME OF THE WEAPONS
THAT ARE SOLD?
SHOULD WE HAVE MORE BACKGROUND
CHECKS?
ALL THESE GUNS THAT THIS GUY HAD
WERE LEGAL.
SO PEOPLE ARE LEFT WITH A BUNCH
OF QUESTIONS IN THEIR MINDS.
>> YEAH.
I THINK IT'S A BIG AND
COMPLICATED QUESTION, RIGHT?
I THINK THERE'S A CULTURAL
PROBLEM WE HAVE.
I THINK WE HAVE -- WE DON'T KNOW
ENOUGH ABOUT HIS FAMILY.
I KNOW THEY'VE BEEN VILIFIED
OVER THE LAST FEW DAYS.
"WASHINGTON POST" HAS AN EVEN
HANDED STORY ABOUT HIS FAMILY
TODAY ON TRYING TO LOOK AT THIS
A LITTLE BIT LESS -- IN A VERY
KIND OF OUTRAGED FASHION WHICH
PEOPLE ARE.
BUT LOOK, I DON'T THINK IN A
FIVE-MINUTE SEGMENT WE CAN
FIGURE OUT WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
I THINK EVERYONE IS TRYING TO
PIECE IT TOGETHER.
BUT TO SAY THAT IF THERE WAS AN
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN IN PLACE
THIS WOULDN'T HAVE HAPPENED, I
THINK THAT MIGHT MAKE US FEEL
BETTER, BUT I DON'T SEE THAT
ANYTHING THAT I'M READING
INDICATES THAT THAT WOULD HAVE
HAPPENED.
WE KNOW WHAT HAPPENED IN
COLUMBINE.
NO ASSAULT WEAPONS USED THERE.
WE KNOW THAT OUT OF 12,664
KILLINGS OVER THE LAST YEAR, 323
WERE COMMITTED WITH A RIFLE OR A
SHOTGUN.
OKAY?
SO AS RICH LOURY POINTED OUT IN
THE NATIONAL REVIEW, EVEN IF
PEOPLE RUSHED FORWARD AND HAD
THIS QUOTE, ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN,
IT'S NOT CLEAR THIS WOULD STOP
THESE TYPES OF KILLINGS.
THERE ARE LOTS OF OTHER WEAPONS
THAT CAN BE USED AND UNLESS YOU
REALLY WANT TO GO FOR AN ALL-OUT
GUN BAN IN THE UNITED STATES,
WHICH IS NOT GOING TO PASS
CONSTITUTIONAL MUSTER, WE
HAVE -- WE'RE NOT GOING TO SOLVE
THIS PROBLEM.
I UNDERSTAND THE IMPULSE, BUT
WE'RE NOT GOING TO SOLVE THE
PROBLEM.
>> Brian: SO THIS HAPPENS,
AURORA HAPPENS, GABBY GIFFORDS
GETS SHOT, OTHERS DIE.
IF YOU WERE IN CHARGE, WHAT
SHOULD WE LEARN FROM THIS
TERRIBLE TRAGEDY?
LET'S JUST BEEF UP SCHOOL
SECURITY AND REIN IN THE VIDEO
GAMES?
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY WE SHOULD
TAKE FROM THIS?
>> WELL, I THINK IT'S A HARD
CALL.
I THINK THAT PEOPLE TALK ABOUT
BANNING CERTAIN TYPES OF
MAGAZINES.
BUT WE KNOW MAGAZINES ALSO JAM.
WHEN THEY JAM, OFTENTIMES THE
PERPETRATOR ARE TACKLED AND
CAPTURED.
TO ME THAT, WOULD BE A SMARTER
WAY TO GO THAN TO SAY OH, THIS
TYPE OF WEAPON.
PEOPLE CAN DO A LOT OF DAMAGE
WITH TEN ROUNDS AND A GLOCK .9
MILLIMETER.
THAT'S NOT GOING TO BE BANNED IN
THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA.
>> Gretchen: WHAT ABOUT THESE
VIDEO GAMES?
THERE HAS BEEN A LOT OF TALK
ABOUT THE FACT THAT KIDS ARE
ACTUALLY EXPERIENCING WHAT IT
FEELS LIKE TO MURDER SOMEBODY
WHEN THEY PLAY THESE GAMES.
>> RIGHT.
>> Gretchen: I HAVE TO TELL YOU
THAT I MADE A DECISION AFTER
THIS HAPPENED FRIDAY TO NOT BUY
A SPECIFIC VIDEO KIND OF PIECE
OF EQUIPMENT FOR MY CHILD THAT
EVENTUALLY HE COULD GET THOSE
KINDS OF GAMES FOR.
IT CHANGED MY MIND PERSONALLY
ABOUT IT.
IS THAT THE ANSWER?
IS IT A MENTAL HEALTH ISSUE?
IS IT ALL THOSE THINGS?
>> I THINK IS THIS YOUNG MAN WAS
OBVIOUSLY SUFFERING FROM
SOMETHING.
I MEAN, I LOOK AT IT AND I SEE
EVIL.
I SEE DEMONIC.
PEOPLE AREN'T USING THE WORD
DEMONIC, BUT I FIND IT TO BE
DEMONIC, WHAT HAPPENED TO THESE
CHILDREN, AND THE IDEA THAT
FAMILIES, GROWING UP AND RAISING
THIS BOY AND SOMEHOW YOU CAN
HAVE WEAPONS IN THE HOME WITH
THIS BOY IN THE HOME, A YOUNG
MAN, HE'S 20 YEARS OLD, THAT
OBVIOUSLY HAS REAL PROBLEMS, I
DON'T UNDERSTAND THAT.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND HOW THERE
WERE WEAPONS IN THAT HOME WITH
THE WAY HE'S BEING DESCRIBED.
TO ME, THAT SEEMS UNBELIEVABLE.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND THAT.
>> Brian: SO THEN YOU WONDER IF
THE BACKGROUND CHECKS ON PEOPLE
SHOULD INCLUDE THE FAMILY.
NANCY, YOU SEEM FINE.
YOU HAVE NO CRIMINAL RECORD.
YOU KNOW HOW TO SHOOT.
YOU CAN HAVE THE GUN.
WAIT.
YOU HAVE AN AUTISTIC SON, WHERE
DO YOU KEEP THOSE GUNS.
HOW DO YOU GET TO THAT LAYER?
>> WE WANT TO RUSH AND SAY, IF
WE PASSED THE LAW, IT WOULDN'T
HAPPEN.
PEOPLE HAVE THE ABILITY TO CARRY
OUT MASSIVE DAMAGE IN THIS
COUNTRY BY PUTTING TOGETHER
THREE OR FOUR CHEMICALS.
THEY CAN DO THAT.
>> DYLAN KLEBOLD AND ERIC HAIRS
HAD BOMBS.
>> WE CAN TALK ABOUT ALL THIS,
BUT UNTIL AS GRETCHEN SAID,
WETBACK WHAT OUR CHILDREN
CONSUME, WHAT THEY LISTEN TO,
WHAT THEY WATCH, THE NUMBNESS
THAT I SEE IN THE CULTURE WITH
KILLINGS ON TELEVISION, WITH
PEOPLE THROWN IN THE BACK OF
CARS ON TELEVISION SHOWS W THEIR
THROATS OPEN, I MEAN, I DON'T
WATCH THIS STUFF, OKAY?
I DON'T ALLOW VIDEO GAMES IN MY
HOUSE.
I KNOW THERE ARE A LOT OF PEOPLE
PLAY THEM, GREAT PEOPLE.
NO PROBLEMS.
BUT FOR ME PERSONALLY, NO MORE
SCREEN TIME.
I THINK THE SCREEN TIME IS
NUMBING THESE KIDS.
>> Gretchen: NO KIDDING.
SUDDENLY THAT 30-MINUTE OF
READING REQUIREMENT THAT MY
KIDS' TEACHER SENDS HOME
NIGHTLY, SOMETIMES IS PAINFUL AS
A PARENT TO GO THROUGH WITH JUST
EVEN TWO KIDS, SUDDENLY THAT
MAKES SENSE.
>> Steve: THERE IS A
CONVERSATION IN LIVING ROOMS ALL
ACROSS AMERICA AND SOON IT WILL
BE IN WASHINGTON AND LET'S
BUCKLE OUR SEATBELTS AND SEE IF
ANYTHING HAPPENS.
>> EXACTLY.
>> Steve: LAURA, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
HAVE A GREAT WEEK AND MERRY
CHRISTMAS.
>> MERRY CHRISTMAS TO YOU AND
INN THE TRUE SPIRIT OF THIS
CHRISTMAS SEASON.
WE'RE SEEING A LOT OF IT PLAY
OUT IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT AND
PRAYERS FOR THE FAMILY.
>> Steve: THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> Gretchen: YOUR HEADLINES.
EMBASSY CHIEF RICHARD ENGLE AND
HIS CREW RELEASED AFTER BEING
KIDNAPPED AND HELD CAPTIVE IN
SYRIA FOR FIVE DAYS.
THEY WERE DRIVING IN WHAT THEY
THOUGHT WAS A REBEL-CONTROLLED
AREA.
COULD HAVE BEEN SAFER.
BUT THAT'S WHEN A GROUP OF 15
GUNMEN WEARING SKI MASKS JUMPED
OUT OF THE TREES AND PULLED THEM
OUT OF THEIR CAR.
THEY PUT THEM INTO A TRUCK,
BLINDFOLDED THEM AND THREATENED
TO KILL THEM OVER AND OVER
AGAIN.
>> WE WEREN'T PHYSICALLY BEATEN
OR TORTURED.
LOTS OF PSYCHOLOGICAL TORTURE.
THREATS OF BEING KILLED.
THEY MADE US CHOOSE WHICH ONE
WOULD BE SHOT FIRST.
WHEN WE REFUSED, THERE WERE MOCK
SHOOTINGS.
THEY PRETENDED TO SHOOT GAVI
SEVERAL TIMES.  WHEN YOU'RE
BLINDFOLDED AND THEN THEY FIRED
THE GUN UP IN THE AIR, IT CAN BE
VERY TRAUMATIC EXPERIENCE.
>> Gretchen: WOW.
THE KIDNAPPERS TOLD ENGLE AND
HIS CREW THEY WERE GOING TO
BRING THOME A HEZBOLLAH
STRONGHOLD WHERE SHE WOULD
EXCHANGE THEM FOR FIVE IRANIAN
AGENTS.
EVENTUALLY THEY WERE FREED BY
THE REBELS.
THEY'RE NOW SAFE IN THE COUNTRY
OF TURKEY.
>>> FORT HOOD SUSPECT MAJOR
NIDAL MALIK HASAN GOING BEFORE A
NEW MILITARY JUDGE TODAY.
THE JUDGE COULD DECIDE TO
REVISIT EVERY RULING HER
PREDECESSOR MADE OVER 17 MONTHS
OF HEARINGS.
THE TRIAL HAS BEEN DELAYED OVER
AND OVER AGAIN FOR THE PAST
THREE YEARS.
THE LAST DELAY WAS OVER DEMANDS
THAT HASAN BE FORCED TO SHAVE
HIS BEARD.
>> Brian: GUILTY.
>> Gretchen: KEY LAWMAKERS ABOUT
TO BE BRIEFED ON THE MOST
DETAILED REPORT ON THE BENGHAZI
TERRORIST ATTACK TOMORROW BEHIND
CLOSED DOORS.
ON THURSDAY, TWO OF HILLARY
CLINTON'S TOP AIDE ALSO TESTIFY
ABOUT THE ATTACK IN FRONT OF
CONGRESS.
THE SECRETARY OF STATE WAS
SUPPOSED TO TESTIFY, BUT SHE
SUFFERED A CONCUSSION AFTER
FAINTING.
DOCTORS SAY IT MAY TAKE SEVERAL
WEEKS BEFORE SHE CAN GET BACK TO
WORK AND THEREFORE, SHE WON'T BE
TESTIFYING NOW.
>> Steve: HOPE SHE'S OKAY.
>> Brian: SHE CAN'T TAKE GYM
WITH A CONCUSSION FOR TWO WEEKS.
>> Steve: 13 MINUTES AFTER THE
TOP OF THE HOUR.
THINK OBAMA IS -- OBAMACARE IS
ONLY FOR PEOPLE?
THINK AGAIN.
HOW THE COST COULD TRIAL BE
PASSED DOWN TO YOUR PET.
THAT IS COMING UP NEXT.
>> Brian: THEN WE'LL UPDATE YOU
ON A FORMER MARINE INCARCERATED
IN A MEXICAN PRISON FOR
ABSOLUTELY NO REASON.
WE'RE PUTTING PRESSURE ON THE
GOVERNMENT TO GET HIM RELEASED.
THEY BETTER GIVE IN SOON
[ Woman ] Ring. Ring.
Progresso.
In what world do potatoes,
bacon and cheese
add up to 100 calories?
Your world.
♪
[ whispers ]
Real bacon...
Creamy cheese...
100 calories...
[ Chef ] Ma'am
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
100 calories...
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
>> Steve: OBAMACARE TAX HIKES
AREN'T JUST GOING TO AFFECT YOUR
MEDICAL BILLS.
THEY COULD ALSO AFFECT YOUR
PETS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
UNDER THE NEW LAW, HEALTH CARE
LAW, SOME MEDICAL DEVICES USED
BY VETERINARIANS WILL BE HIT BY
A 2.3% TAX.
THAT MEANS THAT COST HITTING
YOUR DOG'S DOCTOR MAY BE PASSED
ON TO YOU, THE OWNER.
DR. NEIL SHAW IS FOUNDER AND
CHIEF MEDICAL OFFICER OF BLUE
PEARL VETERINARY PARTNERS.
HE JOINS US NOW TO EXPLAIN.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
>> GOOD MORNING.
>> Steve: OKAY.
FIRST OF ALL, I DIDN'T REALIZE
THAT THERE WAS A TAX INVOLVED IN
THIS THAT WOULD IMPACT DOGS AND
CATS.
>> WE DIDN'T REALIZE EITHER.
WE'VE BEEN ABLE TO ADVANCE
SPECIALIZED VET CARE BECAUSE
FOLKS WANT PET OPTIONS FOR PETS
THE SAME AS THEY HAVE OPTIONS
FOR THEMSELVES.
>> Steve: SURE.
>> SO WHETHER IT'S A KNEE
REPLACEMENT OR RADIATION
TREATMENT FOR CANCER OR REMOVING
A CATARACT, FOLKS WANT THAT FOR
THEIR OTHER FOUR LEGGED MEMBERS
OF THEIR FAMILY.
>> Steve: OKAY.
SOME OF THE MEDS AND DEVICES
USED ON PEOPLE CAN BE USED ON
PETS AND THAT'S WHY PETS ARE
IMPACTED?
>> CORRECT.
WE'VE BEEN ABLE TO DRAMATICALLY
PROVIDE THE SIMILAR SERVICES AND
PROCEDURES FOR PETS AS FOR
OURSELVES AT A SIGNIFICANTLY
REDUCED COST.
WHEN OUR COSTS RISE, THOSE
OPTIONS COULD BECOME
UNAFFORDABLE FOR PET FAMILIES.
>> Steve: YOUR COSTS ARE GOING
TO RISE UNDER OBAMACARE
IMPACTING PET OWNERS.
THE PROBLEM IS THAT IF YOU ARE
IMPACTED AS A JOB CREATOR,
ULTIMATELY YOU'LL PROBABLY HIRE
FEWER EMPLOYEES WHICH COULD
IMPACT PETS.
>> WE'VE BEEN ABLE TO GROW.
WE'VE BEEN ABLE TO HIRE HIGHLY
TRAINED WONDERFUL, TALENTED
FOLKS BECAUSE FOLKS WERE ABLE TO
AFFORD HEALTH CARE OPTION FOR
THEIR FOLKS.
IF THEY BECOME UNAFFORDABLE,
THEN WE WON'T BE ABLE TO PROVIDE
THAT NEED.
>> Steve: THE HIGHER -- I MOON,
PET CARE IS VERY EXPENSIVE.
I MEAN, AT THE END OF MY DOG
CHARLIE'S LIFE, HE WAS FACING
THOUSANDS AND THOUSANDS OF
DOLLARS OF PET BILLS TO EXTEND
HIS LIFE.
SO WHAT YOU'RE SAYING IS AS
PEOPLE, BECAUSE OF THE HIGHER
COSTS ASSOCIATED WITH PET CARE
BECAUSE OF OBAMACARE, PEOPLE
WILL HAVE TO DECIDE, CAN I
ACTUALLY AFFORD TO PAY FOR THIS
SPECIALIZED VET MEDICINE OR NOT?
IF IT'S THE NOT, THAT COULD BE
BAD NEWS FOR DOGS AND CATS.
>> HEALTH CARE IS MUCH LESS
EXPENSIVE THAN HUMAN HEALTH
CARE.
HOWEVER, WE DON'T HAVE A THIRD
PARTY PAYMENT.
SO YOU'RE RIGHT.
FOLKS PAY WITH WHAT MEANS THEY
HAVE AVAILABLE.
IF THERE IS UNCERTAINTY ON THE
FINANCIAL UNCERTAINTY, THEN
THEY'LL HAVE LESS OF A
COMMITMENT TOWARDS THE PET.
IF OUR COSTS RISE, THEN OUR
TREATMENTS, WHICH ARE FANTASTIC,
AND NOW PROVIDED, WILL BECOME
UNAFFORDABLE.
>> Steve: WELL, PEOPLE NEED TO
LISTEN TO YOU BECAUSE NOT ONLY
DO YOU KNOW WHAT YOU'RE TALKING
ABOUT REGARDING SPECIALIZED PET
CARE, BUT ALSO IN RUNNING A
BUSINESS BECAUSE INC. MAGAZINE
NAMED YOU ONE OF THE TOP JOB
CREATORS.
>> WE WERE VERY HONORED TO BE
NAMED AS SUCH AND VERY
APPRECIATIVE OF THAT.
>> Steve: ALL RIGHT.
DR. SHAW, THANK YOU FOR JOINING
US TODAY.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Steve: SOMETHING I DID NOT
KNOW.
ALL RIGHT.
20 MINUTES AFTER THE TOP OF THE
HOUR.
COMING UP, A MAN WITH A SPECIAL
MESSAGE FOR THE VICTIMS IN
NEWTOWN.
HEAVEN IS REAL.
HOW DOES HE KNOW?
BECAUSE HE'S BEEN TO HEAVEN.
THEN WE TOLD YOU ABOUT THIS
FORMER MARINE CHAINED TO A BED
IN A MEXICAN PRISON FOR NO GOOD
REASON.
WE'RE PUTTING PRESSURE ON OUR
GOVERNMENT TO GET HIM RELEASED
FOR CHRISTMAS.
HIS MOM HAS A BRAND-NEW UPDATE.
YOU'LL HEAR IT NEXT
[ Female Announcer ]
YOU CAN MAKE MACARONI & CHEESE
WITHOUT FRESHLY-MADE PASTA.
YOU COULD ALSO CUT CORNERS
BY MAKING IT WITHOUT
100% REAL CHEDDAR CHEESE.
BUT THEN...IT WOULDN'T BE
STOUFFER'S MAC & CHEESE.
JUST ONE OF OVER 70
SATISFYING RECIPES FOR ONE
FROM STOUFFER'S.
ADVIL PM® OR TYLENOL PM.
THE ADVIL PM® GUY
IS SPENDING LESS TIME
LYING AWAKE
WITH ANNOYING ACHES AND PAINS
AND MORE TIME ASLEEP.
ADVIL PM®. THE DIFFERENCE
IS A BETTER NIGHT'S SLEEP.
AND WITH MY BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CREDIT CARD,
I LOVE 'EM EVEN MORE.
I EARN 1% CASH BACK EVERYWHERE,
EVERTIME.
2% ON GROCERIES.
3% ON GAS.
AUTOMATICALLY.
NO HOOPS TO JUMP THROUGH.
THAT'S 1% BACK ON...
[ toy robot sounds ]
2% ON PUMPN PIE.
AND APPLE.
3% BACK ON 4 TRIPS
TO THE AIRPORT.
IT'S AS EASY AS..
-[ man ] 1...
-[ woman ] 2...
[ woman ] 3.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CARD.
APPLY ONLINE OR AT
A BANK OF AMERICA NEAR YOU.
>> Gretchen: QUICK HEADLINES.
THE PRESIDENT OF IRAQ NOW IN A
COMA AFTER HAVING A STROKE.
DOCTORS SAY HE REMAINS IN
CRITICAL BUT STABLE CONDITION.
THEY'VE NOT DECIDED IF THE
79-YEAR-OLD WILL STAY IN BAGHDAD
OR BE FLOWN TO ANOTHER COUNTRY
FOR TREATMENT.
>>> AND 22 BROTHERS OF THE
NORTHERN ILLINOIS UNIVERSITY
CHAPTER FACING HAZING CHARGES
AFTER A FRESHMAN PLEDGE DIED
DURING A FRAT PARTY LAST MONTH.
POLICE SAY THE 19-YEAR-OLD HAD A
BLOOD ALCOHOL CONTENT OF .351,
FIVE TIMES THE LEGAL LIMIT.
>> Brian: "FOX & FRIENDS," AND
EVERYWHERE ELSE ON THE SHOW,
WE'VE BEEN COVERING THE STORY OF
MARINE VETERAN JON HAMMMAR
JAILED FOR MONTHS IN MEXICO.
AFTER SPEAKING TO HIS MOM ON
THIS SHOW YESTERDAY, SHE
RECEIVED THIS PICTURE SHOWING
HIM CHAINED TO A BED.
YES, HER SON.
AS WE REPORTED, HE'S BEING HELD
ON TRUMPED UP CHARGES.
IN AUGUST HE REGISTERED AN
ANTIQUE FIREARM WITH THE U.S.
CUSTOMS.
THEN CROSSED THE BORDER TO CHECK
IN WITH MEXICAN OFFICIALS.
HE WAS TAKING THE GUN TO COSTA
RICA ON A HUNTING TRIP.
OFFICIALS ARRESTED HIM AND THE
OBAMA ADMINISTRATION HAS BEEN
UNABLE TO GET HIM RELEASED.
ARE THEY REALLY TRYING?
JOINING US NOW WITH NEW
INFORMATION THAT WE JUST GOT
THIS MORNING IS OLIVIA HAMMAR.
AS A MOM, THIS MUST BE EXTREMELY
TOUGH FOR YOU.
WHAT'S THE NEW INFORMATION?
>> WE JUST RECEIVED A LETTER
YESTERDAY, AFTER I DID THE SHOW
YESTERDAY, FIRST OF ALL, WE
RECEIVED THAT PICTURE FROM AN
ANONYMOUS E-MAIL IN MEXICO.
AND THEN WE ALSO AT THE SAME
TIME RECEIVED A E-MAIL FROM THE
MEXICAN AMBASSADOR THAT HAD BEEN
WRITTEN TO AND OUR
CONGRESSWOMAN.
IT WAS BASICALLY A COMPLETE
DEFENSE AND ATTEMPT AT A
JUSTIFICATION OF THE ENTIRE
SITUATION.
>> Brian: HERE IS WHAT THE STATE
DEPARTMENT SAID TO YOU.
HERE IS AN EXCERPT FROM IT.
MEXICO HAS STRINGENT WEAPONS
LAWS AND ENFORCES THEM STRICTLY.
REALLY?
U.S. CITIZENS ARE ARRESTED EACH
YEAR UNDER SIMILAR
CIRCUMSTANCES.
U.S. EMBASSY STAFF VISIT,
PROVIDE A LIST OF ATTORNEYS AND
MONITOR THE PROGRESS OF THEIR
CASE.
JOHN'S CASE IS PROCEEDING
THROUGH THE MEXICAN JUSTICE
SYSTEM.
DOES THAT MAKE YOU FEEL BETTER?
>> IT'S DEVASTATING.
IT'S BASICALLY NO HELP AT ALL.
ONE THING IN THAT LETTER, I
DIDN'T OPEN THAT LETTER UNTIL
THIS MORNING.
THEY SPECIFICALLY STATE THAT HE
IS BEING CHAINED BECAUSE OF HIS
MILITARY EXPERIENCE.
SO FOR THE PEOPLE THAT HAVE BEEN
ASKING ME WHY DO YOU THINK HE'S
CHAINED AND NOW WE KNOW.
>> Brian: WELL, WHAT DO YOU SAY
TO THE STATE DEPARTMENT NOW
AFTER GETTING THAT LETTER
ESSENTIALLY TAKING THE SIDE OF
MEXICO AND THEIR STRICT GUN
LAWS?
>> I JUST CAN'T GET OVER IT.
YOU KNOW, AT THE HEART OF ALL OF
THIS, IN THE LETTER FROM THE
AMBASSADOR TO THE CONGRESSWOMAN,
HE STATES THAT ALL FIREARMS ARE
ILLEGAL IN MEXICO, WHICH ISN'T
TRUE.
HUNTERS TAKE WEAPONS INTO MEXICO
ALL THE TIME.
JOHNNY MADE AN ADMINISTRATIVE
MISTAKE.
HE DIDN'T REGISTER.
HE SHOULD HAVE REGISTERED THE
GUN AT AN EMBASSY IN THE UNITED
STATES BEFORE GOING OVER THERE.
SO BASICALLY HE HAS BEEN IN JAIL
FOR FOUR MONTHS CHAIN TO DO A
BED OVER A CLERICAL ERROR.
>> Brian: HIS BUDDY WAS
RELEASED.
CORRECT?
>> EXACTLY.
>> Brian: RIGHT NOW DID SHE YOU
GOT -- YOU GOT TO GET HIM HOME
BY CHRISTMAS.
WHAT ARE YOUR OPTIONS?
HAVE YOU SPOKEN TO AN
INTERNATIONAL ATTORNEY?
>> WE HAVE AN INTERNATIONAL
ATTORNEY WORKING ON OUR BEHALF.
BUT SO FAR MEXICO HAS NOT
OFFERED ANYTHING.
SO THE CHANCES OF HIM COMING
HOME FOR CHRISTMAS ARE NOT
LOOKING GOOD AT THIS POINT.
>> Brian: YOU WOULD THINK THE
STATE DEPARTMENT WOULD BE JUST
AS OUTRAGED AS YOU ARE.
INSTEAD, THEY'RE TRYING TO
JUSTIFY IT.
WHEN YOU SEE THAT PICTURE THAT
CAME TO YOU YESTERDAY, WHAT DO
YOU THINK?
>> I'M SHATTERED.
I WAS JUST SHATTERED.
HE LOOKED SO HOPELESS AND AS A
MOTHER TO SEE YOUR CHILD LOOK
LIKE THAT AND NOT BE ABLE TO
HELP THEM IS JUST -- IT FEELS
OBSCENE.
>> Brian: I WANT TO SHOW YOU A
PICTURE OF THE NEW PRESIDENT OF
MEXICO.
YOU WOULD THINK HE'D VALUE
RELATIONS WITH THE U.S. AND
UNDERSTAND WHAT THE MARINES MEAN
TO US.
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO HIM AS WE
LOOK AT ENRIQUE?
>> AND THIS CASE.
THIS IS WRONG AND DO THE RIGHT
THING.
HE SHOULD BE RELEASED
IMMEDIATELY.
THIS WAS AN ADMINISTRATIVE
MISTAKE.
HE IS NOT A GUN RUNNER AND YOU
KNOW IT.
PLEASE RELEASE HIM.
>> Brian: YOU KNOW, YOU NEVER
ARE A FORM MARINE.
WE HEAR THAT ALL THE TIME.
A MARINE IS IN TROUBLE, MARINES
ACROSS THIS COUNTRY.
THEY SHOULD BE CONTACTING THEIR
CONGRESSMEN AND WOMEN,
CONTACTING THEIR SENATOR.
LETTING THE WHITE HOUSE KNOW
THIS CANNOT STAND AND WE NEED AN
ANSWER BEFORE CHRISTMAS AND GET
YOUR SON HOME.
MARINE ALWAYS, AND THEY ARE A
TIGHT UNIT, THEY SHOULD RALLY TO
YOUR SIDE NOW.
I HOPE YOU FEEL THAT AND FELT
THIS ALONG THE WAY.
BUT ELECTRIC HERE ON IN, THEY
HAVE TO RALLY TO YOUR SIDE.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH, BRIAN.
>> Brian: WELL, WE'RE GOING TO
STAY ON THIS AND OLIVIA, LET US
KNOW WHAT HAPPENS BECAUSE
NOTHING CAN STOP A MARINE WHO IS
MOTIVATED AND THIS I HOPE IS A
CALL TO ACTION.
>> RIGHT.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> Brian: ALL RIGHT.
THANKS.
WE'LL STAY ON THIS.
NEXT, A MAN WITH A SPECIAL
MESSAGE IN NEWTOWN.
HEAVEN IS FOR REAL.
HOW DOES HE KNOW?
BECAUSE HE WAS THERE FOR A WEEK.
HE'S SEEN IT WITH HIS OWN EYES.
HIS BOOK IS NUMBER TWO ACROSS
THE PLANET.
THEN WE'VE BEEN FOLLOWING THIS
STORY FOR WEEKS.
SHOULD TOY MAKERS CREATE AN EASY
BAKE OVEN FOR BOYS?
THE DECISION IS IN
marching band]
[ Male Announcer ]
THE RHYTHM OF LIFE.
[ whistle blowing ]
WHERE DO YOU HEAR THAT BEAT?
CAMPBELL'S HEALTHY REQUEST SOUP
LETS YOU HEAR IT...
IN YOUR HEART.
[ basketball bouncing ]
HEART HEALTHY.
GREAT TASTE.
MMM...
[ Male Announcer ] SOUNDS GOOD.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
NESPRESSO.
WHERE I NEVER HAVE TO COMPROMISE
ON ANYTHING.
♪
WHERE JUST ONE TOUCH
CREATES THE PERFECT COFFEE.
WHERE EVERY CAPPUCCINO AND LATTE
IS ONLY MADE WITH FRESH MILK.
AND WHERE THE STAFF
IS EXCEPTIONALLY FRIENDLY.
♪
NESPRESSO. WHAT ELSE?
GIVES YOU 1% CASH BACK
ON ALL PURCHASES,
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS.
AND EVERYONE LIKES 50% MORE...
[ Midwestern/Chicago accent ]
CHEDDAR! YEAH!
50 PERCENT MORE
[yodeling] YODEL-AY-EE-OO.
50% MORE FLASH.
[ Southern accent ]
50 PERCENT MORE TATERS.
THAT'S WHERE TOTS COME FROM.
[ Male Announcer ] THE
Capital One Cash Rewards Card
GIVES YOU
1% CASH BACK
ON EVERY
PURCHASE
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS
ON THE CASH YOU EARN.
IT'S THE CARD FOR PEOPLE
WHO LIKE MORE CASH.
50% MORE SPY STUFF.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
THIS CAR IS TOO SMALL.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OURENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
>> Gretchen: WELCOME BACK.
NEW DEVELOPMENTS OVERNIGHT AS
LAWMAKERS RACE TO AVOID NOW THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
SO WE GOT WORD THAT THE
PRESIDENT SEEMS TO BE MAYBE
GIVING IT A LITTLE GROUND, TRY
AND MAKE A DEAL.
BUT WILL THE SUDDEN SHIFT BE
ENOUGH FOR REPUBLICANS.
KELLY WRIGHT LIVE AT THE WHITE
HOUSE.
THEY'RE HARD TO COME BY, AREN'T
THEY?
IT'S KIND OF DRIPS AND DRABS.
>> JUST DRIPS AND DRABS, BUT
HOPEFULLY GETTING TO SOME
ANSWERS.
LISTEN, VERY MUCH THEY WANT TO
GET A DEAL DONE.
THAT'S WHY JOINER ACTUALLY CAME
HERE TO THE WHITE HOUSE ON
MONDAY TO MEET WITH THE
PRESIDENT IN ANOTHER
FACE-TO-FACE MEETING.
THEY TALKED FOR ABOUT 45 MINUTES
IN THAT MEETING.
MR. BAIN PUT THE REPUBLICAN DEAL
BEFORE THE PRESIDENT, LET TAX
CUTS EXPIRE FOR THOSE EARNING
MORE THAN A MILLION DOLLARS A
YEAR.
THAT'S A MAJOR CONCESSION FOR
JOHN BOEHNER AND IN A
COUNTEROFFER, THE PRESIDENT
SOFTENED HIS DEMAND FOR A TAX
HIKE ON THOSE EARNING MORE THAN
$250,000 BY RAISING IT TO
$400,000 A YEAR.
HERE IS A ROUGH OUTLINE OF THE
PROPOSED DEAL.
ESSENTIALLY CALLING FOR
$1 TRILLION IN CUTS.
$1 TRILLION IN REVENUE.
SOME OF THAT WILL REQUIRE AN
IMMEDIATE DOWN PAYMENT AND THEN
LEGISLATIVE PROCESSING IT
THROUGH THE NEXT YEAR.
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS ALSO GIVING
IN TO SOME OF THE GOP'S DEMANDS
FOR SPENDING CUTS ON ENTITLEMENT
PROGRAMS SUCH AS LOWERING THE
COST OF LIVING INCREASES FOR
PEOPLE ON SOCIAL SECURITY.
THE CONCESSIONS FROM BOTH SIDES,
HOWEVER, SHOW THEY COULD BE
CLOSE TO A DEAL AND IN A
STATEMENT, BOEHNER SPOKESMAN
MIKE STEELE SAID THEY ARE MAKING
A STEP IN THE RIGHT DIRECTION
ADDING, QUOTE, WE HOPE TO
CONTINUE DISCUSSIONS WITH THE
PRESIDENT SO WE CAN REACH AN
AGREEMENT THAT IS TRULY BALANCED
AND BEGINS TO SOLVE OUR SPENDING
PROBLEM.
>> A COMPROMISE THAT IS -- MEETS
THE PRESIDENT'S PRINCIPLES AND
OBJECTIVES OF DEFICIT REDUCTION
IS DONE IN A WAY THAT PROTECTS
THE MIDDLE CLASS AND SENIORS AND
ASKS THE WEALTHIEST TO PAY MORE
WILL REQUIRE TOUGH CHOICES BY
ALL SIDES.
>> TOUGH CHOICES ON BOTH SIDES
AND WHITE HOUSE PRESS SECRETARY
JAY CARNEY WENT ON TO SAY THE
DEAL, WHEN IT'S FINALLY MADE,
APPARENTLY BOTH SIDES WILL NOT
BE HAPPY WITH IT OR PLEASED WITH
IT BECAUSE THERE WILL BE SOME
GIVING AND TAKING ON BOTH SIDES
OF THE AISLE.
CONGRESS, BY THE WAY, JUST HAS
TWO WEEKS TO HAMMER OUT A DEAL.
TWO WEEKS NOW FROM THOSE
AUTOMATIC SPENDING CUTS GOING
INTO EFFECT AS OF JANUARY 1.
THEY'VE GOT TO GET SOMETHING
DONE.
BACK TO YOU.
>> Steve: KELLY, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
YEAH.
HE'S RIGHT.
BOTH SIDES GIVE SOMETHING, BUT
IT SEEMS LIKE A WASHOUT FOR THE
REPUBLICANS.
I DON'T KNOW WHY BOEHNER WOULD
GO ALONG WITH IT AT THIS POINT.
>> Brian: ONE THING HE WOULD GET
IS THE BAUSCH TAX CUTS
PERMANENT.
THE THING IS THE DIVIDENDS,
INVESTMENT TAX GOING UP WILL BE
DEVASTATE TO GO WALL VOTE.
>> Steve: ESPECIALLY THOSE ON
FIXED INCOMES.
>> Brian: HE WILL BE THE FIRST
AFRICAN-AMERICAN SENATOR EVER IN
SOUTH CAROLINA, REPUBLICAN TIM
SCOTT, A CONGRESSMAN THERE.
GOVERNOR OF SOUTH CAROLINA,
NIKKI HALEY PICKED HIM TO
REPLACE SENATOR JIM
DEMANIPULATE.
>> ONLY IN THIS COUNTRY CAN AN
INDIAN FEMALE BECOME GOVERNOR,
CAN AN AFRICAN-AMERICAN MALE
BECOME U.S. SENATOR BECAUSE
EVERY CHILD NORTH TEXAS MATTER
WHAT RACE OR GENDER CAN GROW UP
TO BE ANYTHING THEY WANT IN THIS
COUNTRY.
>> Brian: SCOTT WILL BE THE
FIRST AFRICAN-AMERICAN SENATOR
IN THE SOUTH SINCE
RECONSTRUCTION.
>> Steve: CONGRATULATIONS.
EXTREME WEATHER LEADS TO A
TERRIFYING NIGHT FOR TWO PARENTS
IN WASHINGTON WHEN STRONG WINDS
SENT A HUGE TREE CRASHING
THROUGH THEIR HOUSE, LANDING
INCHES FROM THEIR SLEEPING BABY.
>> COME DOWNSTAIRS, SEE A TREE
FALL ONTO THE NEIGHBOR'S YARD,
HIT THEIR HOUSE.
IT'S THE BABY'S ROOM.
>> THERE WAS A COUPLE BROKEN
TRUSSES, SHEETING HANGING DOWN.
SO YEAH, IT COULD HAVE BEEN --
I'M SURE IT WAS SCARY FOR THE
PARENTS WHEN THEY WENT IN THE
ROOM.
>> Steve: EASILY.
THE TREE LANDED A COUPLE OF FEET
AWAY FROM THE BABY'S CRIB.
LUCKILY HE DID NOT HAVE A
SCRATCH.
>> Gretchen: NEW JERSEY TEEN
CAMPAIGNING FOR AN EASY BAKE
OVEN FOR BOYS GETTING HER WISH
AFTER MEETING WITH 13-YEAR-OLD
McKENNA MONDAY, HASBRO
INTRODUCE AGO GENDER NEUTRAL
BLACK AND SILVER MODEL NEXT
YEAR.
SHE EVEN GOT TO CHECK OUT OF THE
THE PROTOTYPE.
SHE STARTED HER CAMPAIGN SO SHE
COULD BUY ONE FOR HER LITTLE
BROTHER.
HER ON-LINE PETITION RECEIVED
OVER 44,000 SIGNATURES AND IN
SUPPORT OF CELEBRITY CHEFS --
CELEBRITY CHEFS INCLUDING BOBBY
FLAY.
>> Brian: THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
PICKED ITS MOST MEMORABLE PHOTO
OF 2012.
HERE ARE FIVE.
FIRST, REMEMBER THIS, CAUGHT
TERRORIZING A COLORADO
NEIGHBORHOOD.
A PHOTO PHOTOGRAPHER SNAPPED
THIS PICTURE JUST AS THE
TRANQUILIZED BEAR FELL FROM A
TREE.
>> Steve: NEXT, MEMORABLE MOMENT
FROM THE LONDON OLYMPICS AS A
SWIMMER BROKE THE WATER SURFACE.
LOOK AT THAT.
>> Gretchen: AND THEN THE ICONIC
SHOT OF HURRICANE SANDY'S FLOOD
WATERS FILLING A TAXI LOT.
MOST OF THOSE CABS UNFORTUNATELY
DESTROYED.
>> Steve: THAT'S RIGHT.
WHO CAN FORGET THIS DEBATE?
SPARKS BETWEEN PRESIDENT OBAMA
AND REPUBLICAN CHALLENGER MITT
ROMNEY.
UNFORTUNATELY, THE LIST CLOSES
OUT WITH A MOMENT NO ONE IS
GOING TO FORGET.
HEARTBREAK IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT AS POLICE LEAD A
LINE OF CHILDREN AWAY FROM THEIR
SCHOOL AFTER, OF COURSE, THE
SHOOTER OPENED FIRE.
THAT IMAGE FROM THE NEWTOWN BEE.
>> Gretchen: IN THE WAKE OF THAT
TRAGIC SHOOTING, SOME ARE
TURNING TO THEIR FAITH IN ORDER
TO TRY AND COPE.
OUR NEXT GUEST SAYS IT'S RIGHT
TO HOLD OUT HOPE BECAUSE HEAVEN
IS REAL.
HOW DOES HE KNOW?
HE'S BEEN THERE.
HE IS A NOTED NEURAL SURGEON AND
THE AUTHOR OF "PROOF OF HEAVEN,"
BEST SELLER.
HE'S BEEN ON THE SHOW SEVERAL
TIMES.
PEOPLE KEEP WANTING TO YOU COME
BACK BECAUSE ESPECIALLY NOW IN
THE WAKE OF THIS TRAGEDY, YOU
OFFER HOPE BECAUSE YOU'VE SEEN
THE LIGHT, RIGHT?
>> THAT'S VERY MUCH THE CASE.
MY HEARTFELT LOVE AND PRAYERS GO
OUT TO THOSE AFFECTED BY THIS
TRAGEDY.
>> Steve: SURE, I UNDERSTAND
THAT YOU FEEL THAT WHEN TRAGEDY
HITS A TOWN AND A FAMILY LIKE
THIS ONE DOES, GOD FINDS A WAY
TO HELP THE VICTIMS' FAMILIES.
EXPLAIN WHAT YOU MEAN.
>> VERY MUCH IT HAS TO DO WITH
THE BELIEF AND KNOWING THAT THAT
IS POSSIBLE.
FOR ME IT'S BECOME VERY, VERY
CLEAR THAT THAT ENTIRE REALM AND
THE ETERNITY OF OUR SOULS IS
VERY MUCH A PART OF ALL REALITY.
AND THAT IS SOMETHING THAT I
WANT TO OFFER TO THEM IS JUST
KNOWING THAT THAT BELIEF CAN
OFFER COMFORT AND THAT THEY CAN
KNOW THAT THOSE PRECIOUS SOULS
ARE CHERISHED AND CARED FOR
RIGHT NOW.
AND THAT IS -- IT CAN BE A VERY
COMFORTING MESSAGE.
I'M NOT TAKING AWAY FROM THE
FACT THIS THIS IS A HORRIBLE
TRAGEDY, VERY PAINFUL.
AND I THINK IT'S A WAKE-UP CALL
TO ALL OF US TO GET BACK TO OUR
SPIRITUAL CORE AND TO REALLY
SUPPORT EACH OTHER AND REALLY
BRING MUCH MORE LOVE AND
COMPASSION INTO THIS WORLD.
>> Brian: THOSE CHILDREN WHO
DIED IN SO MUCH HORROR AND
RAPIDLY, WITHIN THREE MINUTES,
ALL THE DAMAGE DONE, DO YOU LET
EVERYONE KNOW WHAT YOU
EXPERIENCED AND WHAT YOU THINK
THEY'RE EXPERIENCING RIGHT NOW.
>> IT'S VERY MUCH ONE OF BEING
WELCOMED INTO COMFORT AND LOVE
BEYOND OUR HUMAN UNDERSTANDING.
THIS IS SOMETHING THAT MANY
PEOPLE, MILLIONS WHO HAVE HAD
NEAR DEATH EXPERIENCES BRING
BACK IS THAT COMFORT IS SO
BEAUTIFUL AND ABSOLUTELY
CHERISHED.
WE GO BACK TO OUR HOME, TO OUR
MAKER.
THAT'S EXACTLY WHERE THOSE
BELOVED SOULS ARE RIGHT NOW.
>> Gretchen: DOCTOR, IF PEOPLE
DON'T KNOW YOUR STORY, YOU WERE
ILL.
YOU WERE IN A COMA.
YOU LEFT THIS EARTH FOR A WEEK.
YOU WERE IN HEAVEN AND THEN YOU
WROTE ABOUT YOUR EXPERIENCES
THERE AND YOU WERE TOLD THAT YOU
WERE SUPPOSED TO COME BACK TO
THE EARTH.
AS PEOPLE ARE GRAPPLING WITH THE
HORRIBLE NATURE OF THIS TRAGEDY,
WILL THESE CHILDREN FORGET WHEN
THEY'RE IN HEAVEN WHAT HAPPENED
TO THEM?
>> THEY WILL KNOW WHAT HAPPENED,
BUT THEY WILL NOT FEEL THE PAIN.
THEY WILL FEEL THE LOVE AND
CHERISHING OF THEIR BEING BACK
THERE.
AND THEY WILL KNOW THAT THEY
HAVE CHANGED THIS WORLD BECAUSE
IT IS ABOUT CHANGING DOWN HERE,
CHANGING THIS WORLD THAT WE LIVE
IN BY GROWING OUR SPIRITUAL
FAITH, BY KNOWING THAT LOVE,
KNOWING THE ETERNITY OF OUR
SOULS, AND KNOWING THAT THIS IS
ALL ABOUT COMPASSION AND
FORGIVENESS AND LOVING EACH
OTHER WITHOUT ANY BOUNDARYIES.
>> Brian: YOUR BOOK AND YOU'RE A
NEUROSURGEON, YOU NEVER BELIEVED
IN THIS UNTIL IT HAPPENED TO YOU
AND YOU WERE BRAIN DEAD FOR A
WEEK AND YOUR FRIENDS WHO WORK
IN YOUR BUSINESS SAY THERE IS NO
WAY YOU COULD HAVE POSSIBLY COME
BACK.
THERE WAS NO ACTIVITY THERE.
WHERE IS THE SHOOTER?
>> THE SHOOTER IS IN A PLACE OF
REVIEWING HIS OWN LIFE --
>> Steve: PURGATORY?
>> WELL, I THINK IT'S WHAT'S
CALLED A LIFE REVIEW IN THE
WHOLE NEAR DEATH LITERATURE.
IT'S A VERY REAL PHENOMENON OF
RELIVING ALL THE EVENTS OF ONE'S
LIFE AND RELIVING THE PAIN AND
SUFFERING THAT WE'VE HANDED OUT
TO OTHERS.
BUT FROM THEIR POINT OF VIEW,
AND IN THAT REALM, THAT PAIN IS
STILL MUCH MORE INTENSE -- FELT
MORE INTENSELY BY THE
PERPETRATOR THAN EVER FELT BY
THE VICTIMS HERE ON EARTH.
I THINK IT'S ALSO A CALL,
THOUGH, ABOUT MENTAL ILLNESS AND
OUR SOCIETY NEEDS TO HELP THOSE
PEOPLE WHO ARE MENTALLY ILL.
THAT IS SOMETHING THAT WOULD
HAVE HELPED IN THIS KIND OF
SITUATION, TO TRY AND HAVE A
MUCH BETTER SAFETY NET TO HELP
THOSE PEOPLE AND SHOW THEM LOVE
AND COMPASSION.
>> Steve: THE BOOK IS CALLED
"PROOF OF HEAVEN."
DR. ALEXANDER JOINING US FROM
VIRGINIA.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH WITH SOME
COMFORTING WORDS FOR THE MANY
FAMILIES WHO LOST SO MANY JUST
LAST FRIDAY.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR
HAVING ME BACK.
>> Steve: THANK YOU.
>> Brian: NEXT UP, REMEMBER THE
OLD JULIE ANDREWS CINDERELLA?
♪
♪ .
>> Brian: WE HAVE A SNEAK PEEK
ON A
. ..
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a
Droid Incredible 4G LTE
by HTC for $49.99.
Hurry in for a
Droid Incredible 4G LTE
It's hard to see opportunity
in today's challenging
environment.
Unless you have the right
perspective.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
has the vision
and experience to look beyond
the obvious.
We'll uncover opportunities,
find hidden risk,
and make success a reality.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
>> Steve: WITH EXACTLY ONE WEEK
LEFT UNTIL CHRISTMAS, MANY OF US
STILL HAVE LAST MINUTE SHOPPING
TO DO.
BUT THAT DOESN'T MEAN YOU HAVE
TO PAY TOP DOLLAR.
>> Gretchen: HERE WITH ON-LINE
SHOPPING TIPS, SAVINGS EXPERT,
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
PEOPLE CAN STILL GET FREE
SHIPPING EVEN THOUGH IT WAS
YESTERDAY?
>> YES, FREE SHIPPING WAS
YESTERDAY.
GOOD NEWS IS, 30 RETAILERS ARE
OFFERING A FREE SHIPPING.
GO TO FREESHIPPINGDAY.COM.
THEY LIST THE DEALS.
GAP IS OFFERING 30% OFF PLUS
FREE SHIPPING.
OR FREESHIPPING.ORG WHERE THEY
HAVE SHIPPING CODES.
>> Steve: ALWAYS COMPARE PRICES
ON-LINE.
THERE IS PRICE DROP.
>> RIGHT.
YOU WANT TO TRACK PRICES BECAUSE
RETAILERS ARE USING DYNAMIC
PRICING, WHICH FLUCTUATES THE
PRICES ON GOODS THROUGHOUT THE
DAY.
HUXTER.COM WILL ALERT IF YOU
PRICES DROP.
EVEN IF YOU MAKE A PURCHASE,
TRACK IT BECAUSE SOME RETAILERS
WILL MATCH IT AFTERWARD.
TAKE A SCREEN SHOT OF THE
PRODUCT, E-MAIL IT OR BRING IT
TO CUSTOMER SERVICE REP.
>> Gretchen: CLEAR YOUR COOKIES
AND WE'RE NOT TALK BEING
CHOCOLATE CHIP KIND.
>> NO.
SO COOKIES SEND DATA FROM YOUR
COMPUTER TO A WEB SITE,
RETAILERS USE THAT TO TRACK
PURCHASES, BROWSING PATTERNS AND
WHAT NOT AND THEY WILL SET
DIFFERENT PRICES BASED ON THAT
HISTORY AND THAT INFORMATION
THAT THEY TRACK.
SO IF YOU CLEAR IT, YOU'LL GET
BETTER DEALS.
>> Gretchen: HOW DO YOU CLEAR
IT?
>> GO TO YOUR BROWSER AND FIND
THE FUNCTION IN THERE.
>> Steve: IT ALL DEPENDS ON YOUR
OPERATING SYSTEM.
AND YOUR FINAL TIP IS MY
FAVORITE.
YOU GO SHOPPING FO A LITTLE
WHILE AND THEN REALIZE, WAIT A
MINUTE.
I'M NOT GOING TO BUY THAT RIGHT
NOW.
THIS IS CALL THE ABANDON
SHOPPING CART SYNDROME.
WHAT'S THAT MEAN?
>> A LOT OF PEOPLE ABANDON THEIR
CARTS BECAUSE ONE, THEY DON'T
WANT TO PAY FOR THE SHIPPING.
YOU PUT IT INTO YOUR CART AND
THEN YOU CHANGE YOUR CART AND
CLICK OUT OF THE BROWSER.
OFTENTIMES YOU'LL NOW GET AN
E-MAIL FROM THE RETAILER TRYING
TO GET YOU TO GO BACK AND MAKE
THE PURCHASE AND SOME RETAILERS
MAY EVEN OFFER YOU A COUPON CODE
TO INCENTIVIZE YOU TO MAKE THAT
PURCHASE.
IT'S NOT THAT WIDESPREAD YET.
WE'LL SEE MORE RETAILERS DOING
IT OVERT NEXT COUPLE YEARS.
>> Steve: THAT'S FANTASTIC.
>> GIVE A TRY IF YOU WANT TO
SAVE EXTRA.
>> Gretchen: WE'LL HAVE MORE
TIPS IN OUR AFTER THE SHOW SHOW
WITH ANDREA IF YOU'RE STILL
LOOKING FOR THOSE SHOPPING
BARGAINS, WHICH EVERYONE
PROBABLY IS.
>> Steve: I WAIT 'TIL CHRISTMAS
EVE.
>> Gretchen: YOU ALWAYS DO.
>> Steve: STRAIGHT AHEAD, A
MODERN TWIST ON THIS CLASSIC
CINDERELLA STORY NOW ON
BROADWAY.
A LIVE PERFORMANCE ON THE "FOX &
FRIENDS" SET.
>> Gretchen: FIRST, LET'S CHECK
IN WITH MARTHA FOR WHAT'S COMING
UP AFTER OUR SHOW.
>> I REMEMBER THAT. GOOD STUFF.
GOOD MORNING.
WELL, THE OLD FISCAL CLIFF,
WE'VE GOT BRAND-NEW INFORMATION
ON WHERE THIS IS HEADED THIS
MORNING AND GETTING QUITE
INTERESTING, FOLKS.
AND TOM RIDGE JOINS US.
WE'LL TALK TO HIM ABOUT MENTAL
ILLNESS AND THE THREAT TO THE
HOMELAND THAT IT BRINGS.
A STUNNING BLOG THAT IS GOING
VIRAL TODAY IS CALLED "I AM ADAM
LANZA'S MOTHER."
WE'RE GOING TO TALK TO TOM RIDGE
ABOUT THIS.
IT IS WORTH DISCUSSING.
WE WILL DO THAT TODAY.
ALSO 20 FRAT BOYS FACE CHARGES
AND THEY ARE SERIOUS ONES THIS
MORNING.
BILL AND I WILL JOIN YOU AT THE
TOP OF THE HOUR.
WE'LL SEE YOU THEN.
[ Male Announcer ]
COUGHEQUENCE™ #8.
WAKING THE BABY.
[ coughs ]
[ baby crying ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
ROBITUSSIN® LIQUID FORMULA
SOOTHES YOUR THROAT ON CONTACT
AND THE ACTIVE INGREDIENT
RELIEVES YOUR COUGH.
ROBITUSSIN®. DON'T SUFFER
THE COUGHEQUENCES™.
>> Gretchen: IN 1957, FAMED
THEATER TUO OSCAR AND HAMMER
STEIN CREATED A MUSICAL VERSION
OF CINDERELLA.
STARRING A YOUNG JULIE ANDREWS.
♪ AND I LIKE IT SO WELL THAT
FROM ALL I CAN TELL ♪
♪ IT COMES DOWN AGAIN
♪ .
>> Gretchen: NOW THE BELOVED
FAIRY TALE MAKES ITS BROADWAY
DEBUT.
JOINING ME NOW, THE STARS OF
CINDERELLA, LAURA AND SANTINO AS
THE PRINCE.
GREAT TO SEE YOU BOTH.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Gretchen: LAURA AND I SHARE
THIS MINNESOTA THING TOGETHER.
AND YOU'VE GOT FAMOUS BECAUSE
YOU WON THAT GREASE AUDITION AND
NOW PLAYING THIS LEADING ROLE.
IS IT HONOR, GLASS SLIPPERS ARE
SO BACK IS THIS.
>> THEY TOTALLY ARE.
>> Gretchen: BEAUTIFUL.
I CAN'T THINK OF ANYBODY WHO
LOOKS LIKE A PRINCE.
WHAT IS THIS ROLE LIKE FOR YOU?
>> IT'S GREAT.
WE'RE TELLING A KIND OF NEW
STORY, BUT STILL STAYING TRUE TO
THE TRADITIONAL AS WELL.
IT'S A GREAT EXPERIENCE.
>> Gretchen: IT OPENS COMING UP
IN JANUARY AND TICKETS ARE ON
SALE RIGHT NOW, FOLKS.
AND THEY'RE GOING TO DO A SONG
FROM THE NEW BROADWAY SHOW
"CINDERELLA."
TAKE IT AWAY.
♪ TEN MINUTES AGO I SAW YOU
♪ I LOOKED UP WHEN YOU CAME
THROUGH THE DOOR ♪
♪ MY HEAD STARTED REELING
♪ YOU GAVE ME THE FEELING
♪ THE ROOM HAD NO CEILING OR
FLOOR ♪
♪ TEN MINUTES AGO I MET YOU
♪ AND WE MURMURED OUR HOW DO YOU
DOS ♪
♪ I WANTED TO RING OUT THE BELLS
AND FLING OUT MY ARMS AND TO
SING OUT THE NEWS ♪
♪ I HAVE FOUND HER
♪ SHE'S AN ANGEL
♪ WITH THE DUST OF THE STARS IN
HER EYES ♪
♪ WE ARE DANCING
♪ WE ARE FLYING
♪ AND SHE'S TAKING ME BACK TO
THE SKIES ♪
♪ IN THE ARMS OF MY LOVE I'M
FLYING ♪
♪ OVER MOUNTAIN AND MEADOW AND
GLENN ♪
♪ AND I LIKE IT SO WELL THAT FOR
ALL I CAN TELL I MAY NEVER COME
DOWN AGAIN ♪
♪ I MAY NEVER COME DOWN TO
EARTH ♪
♪ TEN MINUTES AGO I MET YOU
♪ AND WE MURMURED OUR HOW DO YOU
DOS?
I WANTED TO RING OUT THE BELLS
AND FLING OUT MY ARMS AND TO
SING OUT THE NEWS ♪
♪ I HAVE FOUND HER
♪ SHE'S AN ANGEL
♪ WITH THE DUST OF THE STARS IN
YOUR EYES ♪
♪ WE ARE DANCING
♪ WE ARE FLYING
♪ AND SHE'S TAKING ME BACK TO
THE SKIES ♪
♪ IN THE ARMS OF MY LOVE I'M
FLYING ♪
♪ OVER MEADOW AND GLENN
♪ AND I LIKE IT SO WELL
♪ THAT FOR ALL I CAN TELL
♪ AND I LIKE IT SO WELL THAT FOR
ALL I CAN TELL ♪
♪ I MAY NEVER COME DOWN AGAIN
♪ I MAY NEVER COME DOWN TO EARTH
AGAIN ♪
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
[ Woman ] Ring. Ring.
Progresso.
In what world do potatoes,
bacon and cheese
add up to 100 calories?
ING . .
♪
[ whispers ]
Real bacon...
Creamy cheese...
100 calories...
[ Chef ] Ma'am
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
A Hybrid? Most are
just no fun to drive.
100 calories...
[ Chef ] Ma'am
Now, here's one that will
make you feel alive.
Meet the five-passenger
Ford C-MAX Hybrid.
C-MAX says ha.
C-MAX says wheeee.
Which is what you get,
don't you see?
Cause C-MAX has lots more
horsepower than Prius v,
a hybrid that C-MAX
also bests in MPG.
Say hi to the all-new 47
combined MPG C-MAX Hybrid.
>> Announcer: 'TIS THE SEASON
OF MORE--
MORE SHOPPING,
MORE DINING OUT...
AND ALONG WITH IT,
MORE IDENTITY THEFT.
BY THE TIME THIS HOLIDAY SEASON
IS OVER, AN ESTIMATED
1.2 MILLION IDENTITIES
MAY BE STOLEN.
EVERY TIME YOU PULL OUT YOUR
WALLET, SHOP ONLINE OR HIT THE
ROAD, YOU GIVE THIEVES A CHANCE
TO RUIN YOUR HOLIDAY.
BY THE TIME YOU'RE DONE WATCHING
THIS, AS MANY AS 40 MORE
IDENTITIES MAY BE STOLEN.
YOU CAN'T BE ON THE LOOKOUT
24/7, BUT LIFELOCK CAN.
THEY'RE RELENTLESS ABOUT
PROTECTING YOUR IDENTITY
EVERY MINUTE OF EVERY DAY.
WHEN SOMEONE TRIES TO TAKE OVER
YOUR BANK ACCOUNTS, DRAIN THE
EQUITY IN YOUR HOME, OR EVEN
TRIES TO BUY A CAR IN YOUR NAME,
LIFELOCK IS ON GUARD.
AND WITH LIFELOCK'S 24/7 ALERTS,
THEY CONTACT YOU BY TEXT,
PHONE OR EMAIL AS SOON AS THEY
DETECT SUSPICIOUS ACTIVITY
IN THEIR NETWORK.
LIFELOCK WANTS YOU TO BE
PROTECTED THIS HOLIDAY SEASON,
SO THEY'RE GIVING YOU 60 DAYS
OF PROTECTION RISK-FREE.
>> MY YEARS AS A PROSECUTOR
TAUGHT ME THAT YOU HAVE TO BE
PROACTIVE TO PROTECT YOURSELF
TRUE CRIME,
OF IDENTITY THEFT.
THAT'S WHY I'M A MEMBER
OF LIFELOCK.
>> Announcer: ABSOLUTELY NO ONE
PROTECTS YOU BETTER THAN
LIFELOCK, AND THEY STAND BEHIND
THEIR PROTECTION WITH THE POWER
OF THEIR $1 MILLION
SERVICE GUARANTEE.
IN FACT, LAST YEAR, LIFELOCK
PROTECTED OVER TWO MILLION
PEOPLE DURING THE HOLIDAYS.
AND NOW THEY CAN DO IT FOR YOU.
TRY LIFELOCK'S PROTECTION
60 DAYS RISK-FREE.
CALL THE NUMBER ON YOUR SCREEN
OR GO TO LIFELOCK.COM/HOLIDAYS.
IT ONLY TAKES MINUTES
TO SIGN UP.
USE PROMO CODE: HOLIDAYS.
ORDER NOW AND GET A SPECIAL
HOLIDAY GIFT: A DOCUMENT
SHREDDER TO KEEP SENSITIVE
DOCUMENTS OUT OF THE WRONG
HANDS... A $29 VALUE, FREE!
CALL THE NUMBER ON YOUR SCREEN
OR GO ONLINE AND LET LIFELOCK
PROTECT YOUR IDENTITY FOR
60 DAYS RISK-FREE.