>> GETS INTO THE CLASSROOM,
ONE OR TWO CLASSROOMS AND
STARTS FIRING AT THE LITTLE
CHILDREN.
AT SOME POINT HE HAS TO RUN
OUT OF AMMUNITION.
EVEN IF HE HAS EXTENDED
MAGAZINES, AT SOME POINT HE
HAS TO RELOAD.
SO THE SCENE I HAVE IN MY MIND
IS THESE BABIES BETWEEN THE
AGES OF 5 AND 10, AS THIS
GROWN UP.
THESE ARE CHILDREN WHO HAVE
NEVER SEEN EVIL.
THESE ARE CHILDREN WHO ARE IN
THE FLOWER OF INNOCENCE.
HERE IS A GROWN UP DRESSED IN
CAMO AND STARTS KILLING THE
CHILDREN.
CAN YOU IMAGINE THE CHILDREN
SCREAMING AND THEN HE IS
RELOADING AND THE DEAD
CHILDREN AND THERE IS THE
CHILDREN YET TO BE KILLED AND
IN THIS MOMENT JUST IMAGINE
THE TERROR BEFORE HE KILLS
THEM.
IT IS SO UNCONSCIONABLE.
>> Geraldo: THIS IS A FOX NEWS
ALERT.
I'M GERALDO RIVERA LIVE ON
LOCATION IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTED
CUT.
SCENE OF THE MURDER OF 20
CHILDREN.
SIX ADULTS TEACHING AND CARING
FOR THEM.
AS EXPRESSIONS OF HORROR AND
SYMPATHY POOR IN THIS
PICTURESQUE NEW ENGLAND TOWN
FOR MILLIONS OF AMERICANS FROM
THE WHITE HOUSE, FROM LEADERS
AROUND THE WORLD, EVEN FROM
THE POPE HIMSELF.
WE ASK WHY.
WHY WOULD ANYONE PERPETRATE
THIS TERROR AGAINST
DEFENSELESS CHILDREN?
WHY WOULD ANYBODY MASSACRE
BOYS AND GIRLS WHO CANNOT
COMPREHEND THE DEPRAVED CRIME
EVEN AS IT WAS BEING INFLICTED
AGAINST THEM.
WHAT SOLE COULD DISREGARD FOR
THE PRECIOUS YOUNG LIVES HE
ENDED ON A SUNNY DECEMBER
MORNING IN CONNECTICUT.
SO TODAY AS WE GRIEVE THE TINY
PEOPLE WHO PERISH BY VIOLENCE
DURING THE HEIGHT OF THE
CHRISTMAS SEASON AND A
WONDERFUL TOWN, VIRTUALLY
UNTOUCHED BEFORE FRIDAY BY THE
WICKEDNESS OF THE WORLD.
AND WE PLEDGE OUR SUPPORT FOR
THEIR FAMILIES AND FRIENDS AND
NEIGHBORS WHO WILL NEVER BE
THE SAME MEMORY, INCALCULABLE
LOSS.
WE ALSO SEEK TO FIND OUT WHY
AND WHAT MADE THIS 20-YEAR-OLD
PERPETRATOR THE DEVIL'S OWN
INSTRUMENT OF THE APOCK
APOCALYPSE.
WE BEGIN WITH CRAIG'S REPORT
HOW PANIC BECAME RELIEF OR
MISERY AND DESPAIR FOR THE
PARENTS OF THE CHILDREN OF THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN SANDY
HOOK.
HERE IS CRAIG'S REPORT.
>> I JUST HEARD THEIR GUNMEN
WENT IN AND STARTED SHOOTING
THE ADMINISTRATION AND THEN
WENT FOR THE KINDERGARTNERS.
THANK GOD SHE WASN'T THERE
BECAUSE I DON'T KNOW WHY
SOMEONE WOULD DO THAT.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
>> THEY'RE THE PARENTS, YOU
KNOW, THAT MIGHT HAVE LOST
THEIR CHILD?
>> I HAVE NO IDEA.
I DON'T EVEN WANT TO THINK
ABOUT THAT SO CLOSE TO
CHRISTMAS.
I'M JUST SO HAPPY MY DAUGHTER
IS OKAY.
>> FRIDAY WASTE FRAUGHT WITH
CONFUSION AND EHE SH EMOTIONAL
PAIN.
UNCLEAR WHO PERISHED OR
SURVIVED AMONG 600 STUDENTS.
WE DON'T E. ANYTHING.
THEY ARE NOT BEING SPECIFIC
ABOUT IMAWRKTS OR INJURIES.
WE JUST WANT TO GO HOME.
>> WE ARE SEEING PARENTS AND
TEACHERS ALIKE BEING ESCORTED
FROM THE SCHOOL GROUNDS, TEARS
STEAMING DOWN THEIR EYES,IT'S
TERRIBLE TERRIBLE NEWS.
ANY PARENT WOULD NOD WANT TO
HEAR.
>> YOU CAN TELL US WHAT YOU
ARE BEING TOLD?
OKAY.
A A TRAGIC STREAM OF FAMILY
MEMBERS ABANDONED CARS AND
WALKED THE OTHERWISE QUIET
COUNTRY ROAD NOW CHOKED WITH
EMERGENCY VEHICLES AS DETAILS
OF THE SENSELESS SHOOTING CAME
TO LIGHT.
>> WE'RE SEEIN A NUMBER OF
PARENTS COMING OUT, BEING
ESCORTED BY THE FIRE
DEPARTMENT BY VOLUNTEERS
TRYING TO PROTECT THEM.
OBVIOUSLY MANY OF THEM GRIEF
STRICKEN.
MANY CONFUSED.
NOT GETTING THE FULL KNOWLEDGE
OF WHAT HAPPENED.
>> THE POSTCARD COMMUNITY OF
NEWTOWN ONE OF THE SAFEST IN
THE COUNTRY BECAME A TRIAGE OF
EMOTIONAL SUPPORT.
COUNSELORS OF YOU DENO, MA'AM
DENOMINATION LENDING A
SHOULDER.
>> IT'S BEYOND WORDS.
I HAVE NEVER SEEN THIS BEFORE
IN MY LIFE.
YOU JUST SEE TERROR IN ANYBODY
EPPS EYES.
>> MORE PARENTS AND LOVED ONES
TAKING THAT LONG WALK UP THE
HILL INTO DOWNTOWN NEWTOWN.
LEAVING AFTER RECEIVING GRIEF
COUNSELING FROM PASTORS FROM,
RABBIS.
LOVED ONES, COMING TO OFFER
THEIR SUPPORT.
BUT WHAT CAN YOU SAY?
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO A PARENT
WHO HAS LOST HIS CHILD?
>> STATE AND LOCAL OFFICIALS
CALLED ON ALL STATE TROOPERS
TO ASSIST SURVIVORS OF A
DEADLY SCHOOL COUNSELOR.
GRIEF COUNSELING.
>> A LARGE AMOUNT OF FAMILIES
TOGETHER.
HELPING EACH OTHER THROUGH
GRIEF.
SOME SCREAMING AND CRYING
WHICH COMES TOGETHER WITH
GRIEF SUPPORTED BY APPOINTED
STATE TROOPER FOR ANY OF THEIR
PERSONAL NEEDS.
THE ONCE CHEERY SCHOOL HAS
BEEN TURNED INTO A MORGUE AS
COPS AND THE MEDICAL EXAMINER
RECREATE THE CRIME SCENE.
CONNECTICUT STATE TROOPER
LT. PAUL VAN.
THIS IS A HORRIFIC SCENE.
IT'S A TRAGIC SCENE.
IT'S VERY VERY HEART BREAKING
FOR THE FAMILIES INVOLVED.
IT'S CERTAINLY VERY VERY
DIFFICULT FOR ALL THE FIRST
RESPONDERS AND PEOPLE WHO WORK
HERE.
>> THIS IS GAIL AND THIS IS
PATTY.
I'M JUST HAPPY THAT THEY ARE
OKAY.
I'M SO SORRY FOR EVERYBODY'S
LOSS.
MY HEART GOES OUT TO EVERYONE.
>> DID THEY HEAR ANYTHING?
DO THEY KNOW WHAT HAPPENED?
>>.
NO NOT YET.
BUT I HAVE A 16-YEAR-OLD WHO
WAS AT THE HIGH SCHOOL AT THE
TIME SO HE DOES KNOW.
>> WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO TELL
THEM?
>> I HAVE HAVEN'T REALLY, YOU
KNOW, IT'S HE VERY HARD.
IT'S JUST -- SO.
>> THANK GOD THEY ARE OKAY.
>> YEAH.
THEY ARE.
>> AS ONE PARENT GOES HOME
WITH HER CHILDREN, A SCORE OF
OTHER FAMILIES HAVE AN
ENTIRELY DIFFERENT SET OF
CIRCUMSTANCES.
>>
>> TWO GRANDCHILDREN.
>> GRANDCHILD.
MY OTHER GRANDDAUGHTER WE
CAN'T FIND HER.
WOMAN TOLD ME SHE HAS TWO
GRANDCHILDREN, ONE OF THE
GRANDCHILDREN IS STILL MISSING
THEY CAN'T FIND HER.
>> THE TOLL OF 8 BOYS AND 12
GIRLS BETWEEN THE AGES OF 6
AND 7 SENT SHOCK WAIVES ACROSS
THE NATION AND THE WORLD.
SANDY HOOK FIREHOUSE BECAME A
GATHERING POINT FOR PARENTS
AND FAMILY MEMBERS WHOSE LOVED
ONES WOULD NEVER WALK OUT OF
THE SCHOOL.
>> PARENTS LEAVING THIS
COMMUNITY, COVERING THEIR
FACES HOLDING THEIR HEADS INEE
OF, NOT KNOWING WHAT TO DO
NEXT.
WHAT DO YOU DO?
YOU DON'T HAVE YOUR CHILD
ANYMORE.
SAW ONE WOMAN CARRYING A CAR
SEAT FOR HER LITTLE BABY WILL
NO LONGER OCCUPY THAT SEAT.
IF IT CAN HAPPEN HERE IT, CAN
HAPPEN ANYWHERE.
>> IT'S JUST INCREDIBLY
PAINFUL, CRAIG, THE VICTIMS
ALL FIRST GRADERS AND THE
ADULTS WHO WERE TRYING AND IN
SOME CASES GAVE THEIR LIVES TO
PROTECT THOSE CHILDREN, IT IS
SOMETHING THAT IS APPALLING,
ALMOST BEYOND BELIEF, YOU AND
I HAVE BEEN TO WAR.
WE HAVE SEEN AFGHANISTAN.
WE HAVE SEEN IRAQ.
WE HAVE SEEN SOMALIA.
BUSHED.
THIS IS WORSE.
TELL ME HOW YOU REACTING TO
WHAT YOU ARE SEEING.
>> ABSOLUTELY WORSE.
WHEN YOU ARE OVERSEAS, WHEN
YOU ARE IN A WAR ZONE, YOU ARE
SEEING HORRIBLE THINGS.
YOU ARE SEEING INHUMANE THINGS
HAPPEN TO OTHER PEOPLE.
EVEN LITTLE CHILDREN BUT YOU
ARE IN A WAR ZONE.
YOU UNDERSTAND THAT YOU ARE IN
A WAR ZONE.
THERE IS COLLATERAL DAMAGE.
THIS IS A PLACE WHERE NOTHING
BAD EVER HAPPENS, NOTHING BAD
EVER HAPPENS TO THEIR
CHILDREN.
THEY HAD SO MUCH TO LOOK
FORWARD TO AND IT'S JUST A
HORRIBLE HORRIBLE INCIDENT.
>> IT IS ABSOLUTELY THE WORST
THING EVER.
FOX NEWS CORRESPONDENT MOLLY
LINE HAS BEEN HERE SINCE
YESTERDAY.
I BET YOU, MOLLY, THAT THAT
SEEMS LIKE AN AWFUL LONG TIME
AGO.
>> IT HAS.
IT'S BEEN EXCEPTIONALLY SAD.
WE HAD A CHANCE TODAY TO
FINALLY HEAR REALLY THE MOST
HORRIFIC DETAILS THAT REALLY
PUT INTO CLARITY WHAT THESE
CHILDREN AND THE WOMEN WHO
WERE TRYING TO PROTECT THEM
SUFFERED.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER STEPPING
UP TO THE MICROPHONE TODAY AND
TALKING ABOUT THE WOUNDS THAT
THEY SUFFER ULTIMATELY CAUSED
THEIR DEATH.
HE TALKED ABOUT THE EXAMS THAT
HE PURPOSELY PARTICIPATED.
IN SEVEN OF THOSE EXAMS.
OF THOSE HE SAID THE WOUNDS
WERE THREE TO 11 WOUNDS ON
THESE YOUNG KIDS.
>> SO THIS GUY TOOK THE BUSH
MASTER, THE 223, THE MILITARY
STYLE CIVILIAN VERSION OF THE
M-4.
STUCK IT UP TO THE CHILDREN
AND THEN HIT THEM EACH 3 TO 11
TIMES.
>> THAT'S THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER'S ASSESSMENT.
HE SAID THIS IS WHAT THESE
CHILDREN HAVE SUFFERED.
WHEN HE WAS ASKED ABOUT
CLOSE-UP WOUNDS NOT EVERYONE
HAS SUFFERED THE CLOSE-UP
WOUNDS.
THEY WEREN'T PARTICULARLY A
QUICK THING THAT HAPPENED
AROUND HIS ROOM.
20 CHILDREN, ALL OF THEM.
EACH WITH ALL OF THESE
DIFFERENT BULLET WOUNDS.
HE SAID IT WAS A LONG RIFLE
THAT WAS USED.
THAT DOESN'T ACCOUNT FOR SOME
OF THE OTHER WEAPONS THAT WE
ALSO HEARD MAY HAVE BEEN FOUND
INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
THE AUTHORITIES HAVE BEEN
WORKING TO CLEAR UP THAT HOW
MANY WEAPONS WERE THERE?
SOME OF THE WEAPONS AT LEAST
TO THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER.
THAT'S ALL COMING INTO
CLARITY.
>> CLEAR NOW THAT THE MAIN
MURDERING WEAPON WAS THE
ASSAULT RIFLE?
>> EXACTLY.
THAT'S WHAT THE MEDICINE CALL
EXAMINER SAID SAID TODAY HE
BELIEVES IT WAS A LONG RIFLE.
THAT LEAVES OTHER QUESTIONS AS
TO WHAT WERE THESE GUNS DOING
AND THE GUNS AT THE HOME AS
WELL.
>> STILL NO WORD ON MOTIVE.
>> NO WORD ON MOTIVE.
AUTHORITIES SAID THERE IS SOME
EVIDENCE.
THEY AREN'T SAYING WHAT OR
GIVE THEM DETAILS THAT WILL
LEAD THEM TO THE HOW AND WHY.
THEY THINK THEY ARE ON THE
RIGHT PATH OF GETTING SOME
INFORMATION ALONG THOSE LINES.
>> NO WORD ON A NOTE LEFT
BEHIND BY THE PERPETRATOR.
>> NO WORD AT ALL ON A NOTE AT
ALL.
>> SO WE ARE LEFT TO PONDER
WHY THIS PERSON COULD BE THE
DEVIL'S SPAWN.
WHY THIS PERSON COULD BECOME
SO EVIL, SO WICKED, SO
DEPRAVED AS TO TAKE THESE
LIVES.
>> ANY ANSWER OF WHY STILL
WOULDN'T EXPLAIN THE
SENSELESSNESS.
>> MOLLY LINE, THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> COMING UP, YOU WILL HEAR
FROM PARENTS, FROM RELATIVES,
FROM FIRST RESPONDERS, FROM
EXPERTS IN LAW, PSYCHOLOGY,
AND FAITH AS WE TRY TO MAKE
SENSE OF THIS SENSELESS
ATROCITY, THE SLAUGHTER OF
INNOCENCE THAT HAS FOREVER
SCARRED THIS LOVELY NEW
ENGLAND COMMUNITY.
>> IT SHOULD HAVE NEVER
HAPPENED TO OUR CHILDREN.
THEY WERE VERY LITTLE.
THEY DON'T UNDERSTAND IT'S
HARD AND I GRIEVE FOR THEIR
PARENTS.
I WOULD NOT EVER WANT TO BE IN
THEIR PLACE.
>> IT DOESN'T MAKE SENSE IN MY
MIND AND I JUST CAN'T GRASP IT
YET.
>> IT SETS IN MORE EVERY
MINUTE AS IT GOES BY.
IT DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
ADULTS MAKE THEIR CHOICES.
THESE PRECIOUS CHILDREN, THEY
HAVEN'T DONE ANYTHING TO
DESERVE THESE KINDS OF THINGS.
>> YOU WILL SEE THEM COME
TOGETHER.
JUST LIKE 9/11, THEY WILL PULL
MARK MY WORD.
IT'S A GOOD TOWN.
>> IT'S UNBELIEVABLY TERRIBLE
WE HUG OUR KIDS THIS MORNING.
AND OUR CLOSEST FRIENDS HUG
HAVE THEIR KIDS THIS MORNING.
WE JUST BEEN THINKING ABOUT
THE PEOPLE WHO DON'T.
>> Geraldo: AS PARENTS
ESPECIALLY THOSE OF US WHO
HAVE YOUNG CHILDREN DEAL WITH
THE HORROR OF WHAT HAPPENED TO
THOSE BABIES AND THE HEART
BREAK OF THE GAVE THEIR LIVES
TRYING TO SAVE THEM FRIDAY IN
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY THE
WHOLE HORROR IS MANICALLY FIND
BY A PLACE THAT'S SUPPOSED TO
BE A SANCTUARY FROM THE
SOMETIMES HARD, CRUEL WORLD.
WILL THEY EVER FEEL SAFE
AGAIN?
JOINING US HERE IN NEWTOWN ARE
PARENTS OF KIDS WHO THANK GOD
WERE UNHARMED IN YESTERDAY'S
HOLOCAUST.
THIS IS MARGARET KEYS AND HER
DAD FRED PEN DERGRASS TOM AND
MARRY AND TOM, WHAT'S YOUR
WIFE?
>> AND BETTY PENNERGRAPH.
MARGARET, TELL US ABOUT YOUR
NEPHEW.
IS HE OKAY?
AND HOW DID YOU FIND OUT ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED?
>> OH, THE SCHOOL SYSTEM SENDS
OUT A MESSAGE AND THAT'S HOW
WE BEGAN TO UNDERSTAND WHAT
UNFOLDED ON FRIDAY.
>> AND SO TELL US ABOUT YOUR
NEPHEW AND TELL US WHAT, YOU
KNOW, WHAT YOU HEARD AND HOW
ARE THINGS?
>> IS HE WELL, HE IS WELL.
I THINK HE IS STILL PROCESSING
IT.
FROM WHAT WE UNDERSTAND THE
TEACHER, YOU KNOW, GRABBED
THEM, PUT THEM IN THE SCHOOL,
THE ART TEACHER, LOCKED THE
DOOR THE WAY HE SAYS IT IS
THAT THE GUNMAN CAME TO THE
DOOR AND WAS BANGING ON IT
TRYING TO GET.
IN HE IS FINE.
>> SO THE GUNMAN ACTUALLY CAME
TO HIS CLASSROOM?
>> YES.
>>
>> Geraldo: TELL ME, IN HIS
WORDS, HOW DID HE DESCRIBE IT?
>> JUST BASICALLY HOW I SAID
IT.
HE HAS SINCE MADE TO A NOTE TO
HIS TEACHER, TELLING HER HOW
HE IS LOOKING FORWARD TO
COMING BACK TO SCHOOL AND SEE
HIS SMILING FACE.
>> YOU DREW A SCHOOL.
>> I REMEMBER BEFORE THE
SCHOOL WAS BUILT.
ACTUALLY DICKINSON DRIVE IS --
GOT KILLED THERE ON THE SIGHT.
THAT HE WAS HOW I'M CONNECTED
TO IT.
TO YOU THIS HORROR MUST SEEM
MORE SO AN THE REST OF YOU
WASES.
>> ONE OF THE SEVEN COMIRNL.
PART OF MY FAMILY.
>> NOW, DO YOU THINK IT WILL
ALWAYS CARRY THE WEIGHT OF
THIS HORRIBLE TRAGEDY?
>> IT'S GOING TO BE A LONG
TIME HEALING ON THIS DEAL.
THERE.
>> LONG TIME HEALING.
I WANT TO TALK TO YOU MORE IF
YOU WOULD JUST STAND BY.
WE HAVE A WONDERFUL PANEL ALSO
JOINING US.
YOU RECOGNIZE THIS IS BO
DIETL, ARTHUR AIDALA, TAMARA
HOLDER, ALL ATTORNEYS.
FAMOUS EXCOP.
HAVE YOU BEEN SQUEAKING WITH
LAW ENFORCEMENT HERE.
WHAT HAVE THEY SHARED WITH
YOU.
>>.
AGAIN THAT SUNDAY WAYS WAS ALL
SHOT IN THE HEAD AND A LOT OF
THE SPERS UP HERE ARE NOT
SPEAKING TO ANY OF THE AT THE AE
TIMIVITYIVES.
KIDS WENT INTO ONE ROOM AND
PUNCH WENT IN THERE.
THIS 223 ROUND.
THE VELOCITY COULD GO THROUGH
THREE OR FEWER PEOPLE.
THIS GUY WAS CONTINUALLY
SHOOTING AND THAT'S WHYTH BODY
COUNT WAS SO HIGH.
KID HAD GONE TO THE SCHOOL.
THAT'S THE ONLY CONNECTION SO
FAR THAT I WAS ABLE TO FIND
OUT.
BUT TO SAY ANYTHING ABOUT
THESE KIDS BEING KILLED SO
MANY OF THEM LIKE THAT, THIS
PUNK WAS EMPTYING HIS GUN,
THIS FOLLY IMAK GUN YOU WILL
SEE TRACE THE OWE BALLISTIC
GUN GOES UP IN THE AIR.
BE ABLE TO SEE B.A. LIST
PARTICULARLY IF EIF IT WAS
FULLY AUTOMATIC.
>> BEFORE I TALK TO YOU LEGAL
STUFF, ARTHUR.
I KNOW YOU HAVE A SON IN FIRST
GRADE AS I HAVE A DAUGHTER IN
FIRST GRADE.
WHAT WAS THE FIRST THING YOU
DO WHEN YOU HEAR ABOUT THIS?
>> IT'S AMAZING THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN WHEN YOU ARE A
BACHELOR AND WHEN YOU ARE A
DAD AND I COULDN'T FUNCTION.
THAT'S THE TRUTH FOR THE REST
OF THE DAY.
YOU WERE SUPPOSED TO HAVE A
LITTLE HOLIDAY PARTY AND YOU
CANCELLED IT.
I THOUGHT THE PRESIDENT WAS
SPOT ON YOU MAYOR A DIFFERENT
HAT WHEN YOU ARE A PAINT AND
TAKE THIS.
>> WHEN I SAW MY SON LAST
NIGHT I HELD HIM AITS I TOLD
HIM THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES HECK HUG AND
CISZED BEFORE I CAME TO DO
THIS SHOW TONIGHT WITH YOU
GERALDO, I HUGGED AND KISSED
THEM, IT SHOWS YOU HOW FRAGILE
LIFE IS.
WE WORRY ABOUT SUCH GARBAGE,
WE ARE WORRIED, THESE POOR
PEOPLE.
THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE' LIVES
HAVE BEEN ALTERED FOREVER.
>> Geraldo: WE WILL TALK ABOUT
9/11 AND OTHER HOLOCAUSTS.
BUT GIVE US A COUPLE MINUTES
AND THEN COME BACK HERE.
NEWTOWN, THE SCENE OF A
TRAGEDY THAT WILL LIVE
FOREVER.
AND FOREVER SCAR THIS
COMMUNITY.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
♪
[ Male Announcer ] WHILE YOU'RE
GETTING READY FOR THE HOLIDAYS,
WE'RE GETTING READY FOR YOU.
TIS THE SEASON.
FOR FOOD, FOR FAMILY,
AND NOW, SOMETHING EXTRA --
FOR YOU.
>> MY DAUGHTER EMILY WOULD BE
THE FIRST ONE STANDING AND
GIVING HER SUPPORT TO ALL OF
THE VICTIMS BECAUSE THAT'S THE
TYPE OF PERSON THAT SHE IS.
NOT BECAUSE OF ANY PARENTING
THAT MY WIFE AND I COULD HAVE
DONE BUT BECAUSE THOSE ARE THE
GIFTS THAT WERE GIVEN TO HER
BY HER HEAVENLY FATHER.
>> Geraldo: I TELL YOU I
CANNOT IMAGINE.
MARY PENNERGRAPH.
YOU WERE BROUGHT UP HERE WITH
TOM AND YOUR FAMILY.
>> YES, I WAS BORN AND RAISED
IN SANDY HOOK.
>> DID YOU, I UNDERSTAND,
DURING THE EVENT YOU KNEW
SOMETHING WAS HAPPENING.
WHAT DID YOU HEAR.
>> I HEARD SHOTS.
MY BROTHER CALLED ME ON THE
PHONE AND ASKED IF THE POLICE
WERE AT MY HOUSE.
I SAID WHY WOULD THEY BE AT
THE HOUSE?
THEY SAID THERE WAS A
SHOOTING.
I HAD HEARD THE SIRENS, I WAS
GOING TO CALL MY FATHER.
I DIDN'T AND ONCE I REALIZED
WHAT HAPPENED, I RAN ACROSS
THE STREET TO THE SCHOOL I SAW
MY CERTAIN WITH MY NEPHEW.
I KNEW HE WAS SAFE.
>> AND, YET, THE CRUELTY IS
SOME PARENTS WERE ELATED AND
RELIEVED AND OTHER PARENTS ARE
CRUSHED AND SCARED.
I MEAN, HOW WILL THIS
COMMUNITY DEAL WITH THAT?
THAT'S WHAT MY BROTHER IS
GOING THROUGH.
LIKE CHRISTMAS DAY FOR HIM AND
HELL FOR OTHERS.
I'M EXTREMELY EXCITED AND
HAPPY WITH MY NEPHEW'S WELL
BEING, THERE WERE PARENTS THAT
DON'T HAVE THAT SAME FORTUNE.
AND IT TEARS OUR HEART APART
TO HAVE TO EVEN THINK ABOUT
THAT CLOSE SO CLOSE TO
CHRISTMAS.
IT RIPS AT MY HEART.
I CAN'T SAY IT ANY MORE THAN
THAT.
ELATED.
FAMILY GOING THROUGH A LOT
RIGHT NOW.
THEY WILL BE GETTING
COUNSELING FOR THEIR SON
BECAUSE POST-TRAUMATIC STRESS,
THOSE THINGS THAT COME TO
PLAY.
THEY WILL PULL TOGETHER LIKE
THIS COMMUNITY.
THIS IS ONE HECK OF A TOWN
THIEVES THESE PEOPLE ARE
GREAT.
THE FIBER OF THIS COMMUNITY
WAS WOKEN UP BY THE DEVIL
HIMSELF.
THIS TOWN WILL RISE UP AGAIN.
IT HAS NO CHOICE BUT TO.
THESE PEOPLE STICK TOGETHER.
>> I HEARD ONE OF THE VICTIMS
WAS AN ANGEL IN THE CHRISTMAS
PAGEANT THAT ONE OF THE
CHURCHES DOWNTOWN.
ALL OF HAVING VARIOUS
MEMORIALS.
YOU WORKED IN HOSPICE CARE.
IT'S ALMOST IF THIS WHOLE TOWN
NEEDS HOSPICE CARE.
>> IT'S INTERESTING BECAUSE
HOSPICE CARE USUALLY INVOLVES
PEOPLE WHO ARE DYING AT OLD
AGE.
I WRKD WITH THEM WHEN I WAS 12
YEARS OLD.
DIFFERENT WORKING WITH PARENTS
WHOSE CHILD ISN'T SUPPOSED TO
BE DEAD.
FAMILIES WHOSE CHILD ISN'T
SUPPOSED TO BE DEAD.
IT'S NOT NATURAL.
THAT'S WHAT MAKES THIS
INCIDENT SO MUCH DIFFERENT
THAN ANY OTHER HOSPICE
INCIDENT OR LOSING A LOVED ONE
FOR CANCER, YOU KNOW, AT AN
OLD AGE.
BUT THE DEBATE DEFINITELY
NEEDS TO INCORPORATE THAT.
I THINK OBAMA IS RIGHT ON
THAT.
IT'S NOT A BIPARTISAN ISSUE.
>> Geraldo: GET BACK TO 9/11.
POINT THAT MORE CHILDREN DIED
HERE TODAY OR FRIDAY THAN DIED
IN THE 9/11 ATTACKS.
THE CHILDREN FEWER THAN DIED
ON THE AIRCRAFT.
>> WHEN I HEARD THIS
YESTERDAY.
IT KEPT MIRRORING WHAT I SAW
PALM SUNDAY WITH THE 10 KIDS
BEING SHOT IN THE HEAD.
THIS IS MORE PERSONAL THAN
9/11.
THAT WAS CRAZY.
PSYCHOLOGICAL MISHAP ABOUT
RELIGION.
HERE COULDN'T BE A MOTIVE NO
MOTIVE IN THE WORLD THAT CAN
MAKE AN EXCUSE FOR THESE POOR
LITTLE CHILDREN.
6-YEAR-OLD CHILDREN COWERING
TOGETHER THIS PUNK GOING IN
THERE AND CONTINUOUSLY
SHOOTING THESE KIDS.
THIS CAN'T BE A MOTIVE.
WHEN THEY FIND OUT WHAT MADE
THIS GUY DO, THIS I WANT TO
KNOW AND I JUST CAN'T BELIEVE
IT COULD BE ANY MOTIVE.
>> Geraldo: YOU CAN'T.
DEVIL INCARNATE.
EAT GOOD FATS.
AVOID BAD.
DON'T GO OVER 2000...
1200 CALORIES A DAY.
CARBS ARE BAD. CARBS ARE GOOD.
THE STORY KEEPS CHANGING.
SO I'M NOT LISTENING...
TO ANYONE BUT MYSELF.
I KNOW BETTER NUTRITION
WHEN I SEE IT:
GREAT GRAINS.
GREAT GRAINS CEREAL STARTS
WHOLE AND STAYS WHOLE.
SEE THE SEAM?
MORE PROCESSED FLAKES LOOK
NOTHING LIKE NATURALRAINS.
YOU CAN'T ARGUE WITH
NUTRITION YOU CAN SEE.
GREAT GRAINS.
SEARCH GREAT GRAINS
AND SEE FOR YOURSELF.
FOR MULTI GRAIN FLAKES TT ARE
ANXCELLENT SOURCE OF FIBER
TRY GREAT GRAINS
BANANA NUT CRUNCH
AND CRANBERRY ALMOND CRUNCH.
♪ Music
Kids will spend
22 minutes watching us,
the Super Duper Party Troopers,
sing about ants in their pants.
Brushing for two minutes now,
can save your child from
severe tooth pain later.
Two minutes twice a day.
They have the time.
THIS IS A FOX NEWS ALERT.
I'M MARIANNE FLARST NEW YORK.
WE WILL GET TO THE TRAGEDY IN
A MOMENT.
TWO BREAKING STORIES TO TELL
YOU ABOUT AT THIS HOUR.
NEWPORT BEACH, CALIFORNIA
POLICE HAVE TAKEN A SUSPECT
INTO CUSTODY AFTER SHOTS WERE
FIRED OUTSIDE A SHOPPING MALL.
THE MAN SHOT INTO THE AIR AND
TRIED TO ESCAPE BY CAR BUT
IMMEDIATELY TAKEN DOWN BY BIKE
POLICE.
THE SHOOTING FORCING STORES TO
LOCKDOWN.
NO ONE WAS SERIOUSLY INJURED.
AND FOX NEWS CONFIRMING
REPORTS THAT HOUSE SPEAKER
JOHN BOEHNER HAS OFFERED TO
ALLOW TAX RATES CONTINUE TO
CREASE FOR WEALTHY AMERICANS
THAT'S THOSE EARNING 1 MILLION
OR MORE.
THIS IN EXCHANGE BOEHNER IS
ASKING THE WHITE HOUSE FOR
SPENDING CUTS, FAX REFORM AND
ENTITLEMENT REFORM.
SOURCES SAY THE WHITE HOUSE
HAS NOT ACCEPTED THE SPEAKER'S
OFFER, BUT SEES IT AS
PROGRESS.
BOTH SIDES ARE TRYING TO AVOID
AUTOMATIC TAX HIKES ON
JANUARY 1st.
I'M MARIANNE RAFFERTY, NOW
BACK TO GERALDO AT LARGE
COMING TO YOU LIVE FROM NEW
TOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> DIFFERENT QUIET, NICE KID,
GOOD KID.
CHALLENGES IN THAT HOUSE.
EVERY FAMILY HAS ONE, I HAVE
ONE, THEY HAVE ONE.
NEVER IN TROUBLE WITH THE LAW.
NEVER IN TROUBLE WITH
ANYTHING.
I KNOW SHE HAD ISSUES WITH
SCHOOL SHE WOUND UP HOME
SCHOOLING HIM.
SHE BATTLED THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT.
I'M NOT 100% CERTAIN IF IT WAS
BEHAVIOR OR LEARNING
DISABILITY, I REALLY DON'T
KNOW.
IS HE A VERY VERY BRIGHT BOY.
HE WAS SMART.
A LOT OF QUESTIONS ABOUT THE
NEPHEW SHE CALLS A BRIGHT BOY.
A YOUNG MAN WHO BECAME A
MONSTER, WHO COMMITTED A
MONSTROUS ACT SMALL
PICTURESQUE CONNECTICUT TOWN
FOREVER MORE WILL BE
ASSOCIATED NOW SADLY WITH THE
MASSACRE OF THE LITTLE FIRST
GRADE KID.
THEIR PRINCIPAL, THEIR SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST AND OTHER ADULTS
TRYING TO PROTECT THOSE
CHILDREN ALL SLAUGHTERED BY
THAT YOUNG MAN TURNED MONSTER
ADAM LANZA.
MIKE TOBIN IS NEAR THE HOME
THE 20-YEAR-OLD SHARED WITH
HIS MOTHER NANCY WHO WAS THE
FIRST TO FALL FROM ORGY OF
VIOLENCE.
TELL US FIRST OF ALL, SINGLE
MOM, DIVORCED, TELL US A
LITTLE BIT.
>> THEY WERE DIVORCED IN 2009
AFTER 17 YEARS OF MARRIAGE
THIS MAY VERY WELL END UP
PLAYING A ROLE.
INDICATIONS THAT BOTH OF THE
SONS WERE TRAUMA ADVERTISED BY
THIS DIVORCE.
AND YOU HAD RYAN, THE OLDER
SON GO OFF TO THE UNIVERSITY.
AND THEN ADAM WAS LEFT ALONE
IN THE HOUSE WITHOUT HIS
BROTHER, WITHOUT HIS FATHER.
AND APPARENTLY WITHOUT A LOT
OF CONTACT WITH HIS FATHER.
NOT A BAD HOME BUT PRETTY
ROUGH ON THE TWO SONS ONCE
THAT FAMILY SPLIT UP.
>> MIKE, WHAT ABOUT THIS
NOTION THAT THE MOTHER WAS A
SURVIVALIST?
THAT'S WHY SHE HAD ALL THESE
WEAPONS INCLUDING THE 223 BUSH
MASTER A WEAPON WHO ARE SUITED
FOR WAR THAN ANYTHING ELSE.
WALLS SHE A SURVIVALIST?
>> WHAT WE ARE HEARING MORAL
IS THAT SHE HAD THE GUNS
BECAUSE SHE LIVED IN THAT BIG
HOUSE PRACTICALLY BY HERSELF.
SHE WAS THERE WITH THE ONE SON
AS WE TALKED ABOUT
DEVELOPMENTAL DISORDERS.
THAT'S WHY SHE HAD THE GUN.
SHE WAS PROUD OF HER GUN
COLLECTION.
RESTAURANT BAR HERE LOCALLY
THAT SHE WOULD -- I WOULDN'T
SAY FREQUENT.
WASN'T A BIG DRINKER.
SHE WOULD GO IN FROM TIME TO
TIME AND SHE WOULD BOAST ABOUT
HER GUN COLLECTION.
SHE WAS QUITE PROUD THROUGH
SOME THE REPORTING THROUGH
REUTERS THAT A LANDSCAPER CAME
THROUGH THERE AND SHE HAD
SHOWED HIM SOME OF THE GUNS
AND TALKED WITH HIM ABOUT HOW
OFTEN SHE WOULD TAKE THE KID
OUT SHOOTING, GERALDO.
>> Geraldo: YOU MENTIONED THE
PSYCHOLOGICAL DISORDER ALLEGED
THIS 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA
HAD.
WAS HE?
WAS HE NOT AUTISTIC?
IS THAT CONFIRMED?
>> IT ISN'T CONFIRMED.
CERTAINLY NOT THROUGH THE
STATE POLICE.
WE HAVE HEARD MENTION OF AS
BERGER SYNDROME A FORM OF
AUTISM.
THAT REALLY GETS TRACED BACK
TO THE OLDER BROTHER RYAN
REPORTEDLY WHAT HE SAID TO THE
POLICE.
OTHER THAN THAT A LOT OF
PEOPLE KNEW HIM AND SOMETHING
GOING ON WITH THAT CHILD --
THAT YOUNG MAN WHO IS INVOLVED
IN THIS TERRIBLE TERRIBLE ACT
THAT HE WAS VERY WITHDRAWN.
SOMETIMES HE WOULD WITHDRAW TO
THE POINT WHERE HE WAS NO
LONGER FUNCTIONAL IN SCHOOL.
HE HAD PROBLEMS WITH SCHOOL.
PEOPLE WOULD SEE HIM IN THE
HALLWAYS.
HE WOULDN'T MAKE EYE CONTACT.
HE WOULD PULL BACK AND CLUTCH
HIS BRIEFCASE HE WOULD CARRY
WITH HILL.
HIS OLDER BROTHER HAD
DESCRIBED HIM AS A NERD
BECAUSE THE INTERESTING THING
IS HE HE WAS BRILLIANT WITH
COMPUTERS.
HE WAS KIND OF SLIGHT OF
BUILD, WALKED AROUND WITH A
POCKET PROTECTER AND THAT'S
WHERE YOU GET THAT KIND OF
LABEL AND HE CERTAINLY HAD
SOME SOCIAL PROBLEMS AT THE
SAME TIME.
HE DID HAVE GIFTS IN TERMS OF
WORKING WITH COMPUTERS.
>> Geraldo: MIKE, THANKS.
DR. KEITH ABLOW JOINS US NOW.
DR. KEITH IS AS YOU KNOW ON
THE FOX NEWS MEDICAL A TEAM.
SO, DR. ABLOW, WHAT ABOUT --
FIRST OF ALL, I NEVER HEARD OF
AUTISM OR AS BERGERES BEING
ASSOCIATED WITH VIOLENCE.
ARE WE SLANDERING THOSE WHO
HAVE THIS DEVELOPMENTAL
DISABILITY?
USING IT IN THIS CONTEXT.
>> GERALDO, BY AND LARGE AS
BERGER'S SYNDROME AND AUTISM
IS NOT ASSOCIATED WITH
HORRIFIC ACTS OF VIOLENCE.
THESE KIDS CAN BE
SELF-ABUSIVE.
THEY CAN BE VIOLENT AT TIMES
THE KIND HE METHODICAL
PLANNING INVOLVED HERE.
THE VIOLENT USE OF WEAPONS,
THE ABILITY TO TAKE THESE
THINGS FROM HIS MOTHER TO KILL
HIS MOTHER TO SAMINGLY PLAN
THEM IS NOT TYPICAL OF THAT
AND THERE HAS TO BE SOME
EXPLANATION OTHER THAN THOSE
DIAGNOSES.
SO, IN THAT WAY, YES, WE ARE
DOING A DISSERVICE BECAUSE
THAT DOESN'T EXPLAIN WHAT
HAPPENED HERE.
IT'S ANOTHER PSYCHOLOGICAL OR
PSYCHIATRIC DISORDER OR SET OF
SYMPTOMS.
>> I KNOW A LOT OF GUN
COLLECTORS THEY USUALLY DON'T
COLLECT WEAPONS BIKE THE BUSH
MASTER THE GLOCK, THE SIG SO
YOUIER.
THESE WEAPONS ARE WEAPONS OF
SEVERE VIOLENCE.
THESE ARE AGGRESSIVE WEAPONS,
PARTICULARLY THE CIVILIAN
VERSION OF THE M-4.
WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF IT?
IF SHE WASN'T A SURVIVALIST,
WHAT WAS SHE.
>> IT'S HARD TO SAY RIGHT NOW
BECAUSE WE NEED MORE
INFORMATION.
AND PEOPLE CAN COLLECT ANY
GUNS THEY WANT.
SHE MAY HAVE HAD ALL KINDS OF
REASONS FOR WANTING THOSE
AROUND.
WHY SHE WOULD GIVE HER SON
ACCESS TO THEM AND NOT HAVE
THEM LOCKED UP WHEN IS HE A
TROUBLED YOUNG MAN AND SHE
KNOWS THAT HE IS WITHDRAWN AND
HAS SEVERE DIFFICULTIES,
THAT'S ANOTHER QUESTION.
THAT DOESN'T REALLY SPEAK YOU
THINK YOU WOULD WANT TO
SAFEGUARD THOSE THINGS FROM AN
AEMOTIONALLY DISTURBED YOUNG
MAN.
DID YOU GET HIM THE HELP IN
ABSOLUTELY EVERY WAY THAT HE
NEEDED FROM A SYSTEM BY THE
WAY, THE MENTAL HEALTHCARE
SYSTEM WHICH IS A NATIONAL
EMBARRASSMENT, A TRAVESTY.
ALL BUT DOESN'T EXIST.
SO, WE WILL SEE MORE OF THIS
UNTIL WE GET SERIOUS ABOUT
CREATING A MENTAL HEALTHCARE
SYSTEM IS AMERICA THAT CAN
SERVE THE NEEDS OF OUTLIERS,
PARTICULARLY THOSE BROKEN TO
VIOLENCE.
WE DO NOT HAVE THAT SYSTEM NOT
EVEN CLOSE I'M TELLING YOU I'M
A VISTA.
D-MINE NEWS GRADE IN AMERICA
AS TO THE MENTAL HEALTHCARE
SYSTEM.
>> I WANT TO TALK MORE ABOUT
THAT AND TALK MORE ABOUT IF
YOU SEE SOMETHING, SOMEONE
BEHAVING IN ABERRANT WAY YOU
HAVE TO SAY SOMETHING.
I KNOW IT'S A CLICHE.
THE QUESTION I HAVE FOR Y'ALL
WHEN WE COME BACK.
WHAT ABOUT MY IDEA THAT THERE
SHOULD BE A COP.
WE SHOULD PROTECT OUR CHILDREN
WITH THE SAME VIGOR WE PROTECT
OUR GOLD, OUR BANKS, WE SHOULD
HAVE AN ARMED COP AT EVERY
SINGLE SCHOOL OVER A CERTAIN
SIZE?
THE KIDS WILL GET USED TO THE
COP.
IT WILL BE LIKE OFFICER CRUMP
CAN
CRUMPKE.
WE HAVE GOT TO KEEP SAFE.
THE SURVIVORS AMONG CHILDREN
AND PARENTS HAVE THEIR OWN
CROSSES TO BEAR GOING FORWARD
TO CHRISTMAS AND BEYOND.
HOW WILL THEY COPE?
AND ONE WAY OF LOOKING HOW THE
FAMILIES OF THE SLAIN CHILDREN
WILL BE EVENTUALLY ABLE TO
HEAL THEMSELVES OR NOT, A MOM
WHO LOST HER SON IN COLUMBINE
IS MY NEXT GUEST.
There is no
mass-produced human.
So we created the
extraordinarily
comfortable Sleep Number
Experience.
around a bed with DualAir
Technology that allows you
to adjust to the support
your body needs - each of
your bodies.
Our sleep professionals will
help you find
your sleep number setting.
Exclusively at a Sleep
Number store.
Sleep Number.
Comfort individualized.
This holiday season, give
the gift that's magical:
the innovative AirFit
adjustable pillow at
special 30% savings.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT STARTED LONG AGO.
THE JOY OF GIVING SOMETHING
EVERYTHING YOU'VE GOT.
IT TAKES PASSION.
AND IT'S NOT LETTING UP
ANYTIME SOON.
AT UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company,
WE UNDERSTAND THAT COMMITMENT.
AND ALWAYS HAVE.
SO DOES AARP,
AN ORGANIZATION
SERVING THE NEEDS
OF AMERICANS 50 AND OVER
FOR GENERATIONS.
SO IT'S NO SURPRISE
MILLIONS HAVE CHOSEN
AN AARP Medicare Supplement
Insurance Plan,
INSURED BY UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company.
LIKE ALL STANDARDIZED
MEDICARE SUPPLEMENT PLANS,
THEY HELP COVER
SOME OF THE EXPENSES
MEDICARE DOESN'T PAY.
AND SAVE YOU UP TO THOUSANDS
IN OUT-OF-POCKET COSTS.
TO FIND OUT MORE,
REQUEST YOUR
FREE DECISION GUIDE.
CALL OR GO ONLINE TODAY.
AFTER ALL,
WHEN YOU'RE GOING THE DISTANCE,
IT'S NICE TO HAVE
THE EXPERIENCE AND COMMITMENT
TO GO ALONG WITH YOU.
KEEP DREAMING. KEEP DOING.
GO LONG.
>> I WAS REALLY KIND OF MAYHEM
IN THE ROOM WITH ALL THE KIDS
AND THE TEACHERS TRYING TO
FIND YOUR KID, FIND WHERE
YOURS IS.
MAKING SURE WHAT THE SITUATION
SAND MAKE SURE EVERYBODY SELLS
SAFE.
FRIDAY'S IS AMONG THE WORST
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
>> IT DOESN'T NOT SEEM LIKE
IT'S EVEN POSSIBLE.
IT'S LIKE YOU, YOU KNOW, YOU
READ IT IN THE PAPER.
SEE IT IN THE NEWS AND YOU ARE
LOOK OH MY GOD THAT POOR
FAMILY AND THEN SOMETHING
HAPPENS SO CLOSE TO HOME IT'S
LIKE I THINK I'M STILL IN
SHOCK TO BE HONEST WITH YOU.
>> Geraldo: LATEST IN THE A
DREADFUL SERIES OF MASS
MURDERS.
BEGINNING WITH COLUMBINE HIGH
SCHOOL IN LITTLETON COLORADO
IN 1999.
12 STUDENTS AND A TEACHER ARE
MURDERED.
24 MORE ARE INJURED BY
CLASSMATES HARRIS AND CLEBO.
>> NOBODY WAS SCARED OF THESE
PEOPLE.
>> NO WE ARE IN THE BUSHES FOR
BARBS FOR GOD'S SAKE.
THIS WAS A SAFE PLACE.
>> Geraldo: A WITNESS HEARING
ERIC YELLING GO, GO.
>> AT FIRST I DIDN'T KNOW IT
WAS REAL UNTIL I SEEN ONE MICH
FRIENDS LAYING THERE IN SOME
BLOOD.
>> ARMED WITH PIPE BOMBS AND
SEMIAUTOMATIC PARTICULAR THE
PAIR TARGETING ANYONE AND
EVERYONE.
AFTER 49 AGONIZING MINUTES IT
ENDS WITH THE SUICIDES OF BOTH
IN THE SCHOOL'S LIBRARY.
IN APRIL OF 2002, ROBERT
STEINHAUSER, A 19-YEAR-OLD
EXPELLED FROM HIS SCHOOL IN
JEARNL OPENS FIRE, KILLING 13
TEACHERS.
TWO FORMER CLASSMATES AND A
POLICEMAN.
DONING A BLACK NINJA STYLE
OUTFIT WHICH HAS BECOME THE
UNIFORM OF CHOICE FOR NIECE
LUNATICS THIS GOWN MAN TARGETS
TEAMERS REPORTEDLY AS REVENGE
FOR HIS RECENT EXPULSION.
FIVE YEARS LATER BACK ON OUR
SHORES THE CAMPUS OF VIRGINIA
TECH IS THE SCENE OF THE WORST
EVER SLAUGHTER BY A SINGLE
GUNMAN ON A SCHOOL CAMPUS IN
U.S. HISTORY.
>> HE OPENED OUR DOOR AND
STARTED SHOOTING PROFESSOR AND
CLASSMATES.
>> ENGLISH MAJOR KILLS 32 AND
WOUNDS 15 OTHERS IN TWO
SEPARATE ATTACKS.
>> AND THAT TIME WE HEARD THE
GUNSHOTS AND WE COULD HEAR
SCREAMS.
AND IT WAS HORRIBLE.
AND THEN WE SAW AS WE POLICE
SWARM THE BUILDING.
I WAS CALLING MY FRIENDS TO
TELL THEM WHEREVER THEY WERE
TO STAY PUT.
>> TWO YEARS PRIOR HE HAD BEEN
ACCUSED OF STOCKING TWO FEMALE
STUDENTS AT WHICH TIME HE WAS
ORDERED TO ATTEND ANGER
MANAGEMENT.
DIAGNOSED WITH SEVERE ANXIETY
DISORDER.
>> BASED ON THAT INTERACTION
WITH THE COUNSELOR.
I A TEMPORARY DETENTION ORDER
WAS OBTAINED AND TAKEN TO A
MEDICAL HEALTH FACILITY.
>> FEDERAL PRIVACY LAW
PREVENTS VIRGINIA TECH FROM
LEARNING THE SEVERITY OF
SEUNG-HUI CHO'S CONDITION.
>> AS I UNDERSTAND IT FROM OUR
LEGAL COUNSEL EVEN THE PARENTS
CANNOT REVEAL OR HAVE THAT
INFORMATION SHARED.
>> IN FINLAND, SEVEN MONTHS
LATER ANOTHER SCHOOL SHOOTING
RESULTING IN A FATALITY.
>> IT'S VERY SAD THAT
HAPPENED.
>> THE PERPETRATOR AN
18-YEAR-OLD STUDENT WHO POLICE
SAY WAS FREQUENTLY BULLIED BUT
WHO OFFICIALS DESCRIBE AS A
MILITANT RADICAL.
>> THE PRELIMINARY ANNUAL CYST
WHICH WE HAD OF THE OFFENDER
IS THAT HE IS QUITE A LONELY
PERSON.
HE HAS A GREAT SOCIETY.
AND OUT OF EXTREME OPINIONS
AND RADICAL THOUGHTS.
>> ALVIN THEN POSTS A PHOTO OF
HIMSELF ON YOUTUBE HOLDING A
GUN ON ONE HAND AND WEARING A
T-SHIRT THAT READS:  HUMANITY
IS OVERRATED.
WHICH BRINGS US BACK TO
NEWTOWN.
>> WE WERE JUST IN THE MIDDLE
OF GYM WHEN WE HEARD SOME
GUNSHOTS AND THEN THE PAIR
WENT OUT AND THE GYM TEACHERS
DIRECTED US TO STAY AGAINST
THE WALL AND EVERYBODY STARTED
KIND OF PANICKING.
WE HEARD A LOT MORE GUNSHOTS
AND THE AMBULANCE CAME.
THEN THE POLICEMAN DIRECTED US
TO RUN OUT OF THE BUILDING AND
GO TO THE FIRE DEPARTMENT.
>> THE COLUMBINE MASSACRE IN
1999 MADE US ALL UNDERSTAND
THAT OUR SCHOOLS ARE NO LONGER
SAFE HAVENS.
BETH LOST HER DAUGHTER RACHEL.
SHE JOINS ME ON THE PHONE FROM
COLORADO.
THANK YOU SO MUCH, BETH, FOR
BEING WITH US.
>> HOW DO YOU EVER HEAL FROM
SOMETHING LIKE THAT?
>> IT TAKES A LONG LONG TIME.
I DESCRIBED IT AS BEING HIT BY
A FREIGHT TRAIN AND YOU DON'T
EVEN KNOW HOW HARD YOU HAVE
BEEN HIT.
AND FOR YEARS YOU CAN WALK
AROUND WITH THE PAIN AND
BROKENNESS OF THAT.
AND BUT, YOU KNOW, IT COMES
AND GOES.
AND FOR US, IT WAS A VERY LONG
HEALING PROCESS.
BUT WE DID ACTUALLY BECOME
STRONGER FOR IT.
AND SOME GOOD THINGS HAVE COME
OUT OF IT.
AND ALL THE TALK ABOUT EVIL,
EVIL SHOWED ITS FACE THAT DAY
AND I CAN HONESTLY SAY IT
DIDN'T WIN BECAUSE OUT OF
LOSING RACHEL, WE ALSO GAINED
A PLATFORM FOR MUCH GOOD.
FIRST OF ALL FOR OUR FAITH,
WHICH SUSTAINED US DURING THIS
TIME AND ALSO FOR PROGRAMS AND
A LOT OF SPEAKING REGARDING
COMPASSION AND KINDNESS AND
BEEN INVOLVED IN A LOT OF
SCHOOLS AND CHURCHES AND YOUTH
PROGRAMS TO DO THAT AND THAT
BROUGHT SOME HEALING.
BUT IT IS A VERY LONG LONG
PROCESS.
THERE IS A LIGHT AT THE END OF
THE TUNNEL, BUT THE PARENTS
THAT ARE THERE RIGHT NOW,
THERE IS NO WAY THAT THEY CAN
EVEN SEE A GLIMMER OF HOPE
BECAUSE OVERWOMENNING DESPAIR
OF THEIR LOSS.
AND MY HEART IS VERY HEAVY FOR
THEM BECAUSE I KNOW THE ROAD
THAT THEY ARE GOING TO TRAVEL
FOR MANY MONTHS AND YEARS IS
GOING TO BE VERY HARD AND
DIFFICULT ROAD I BELIEVE THEY
WILL MAKE IT AND I BELIEVE THE
COMMUNITY HAS ALSO SHOWN
ITSELF TO BE STROCK AND
RESILIENT.
AND ONE THAT WILL.
>> STRONG AND RESILIENT?
>> YES.
>> IT'S A VERY BIG BURDEN.
I HAVE TO LEAVE IT THERE,
RACHEL.
THE AUDIO ON YOUR PHONE CALL A
LITTLE MUDDLED.
I WISH YOU THE BEST AND I
CALLED YOU RACHEL.
BETH, I WISH YOU THE BEST.
OUR CONDOLENCES FOR THE LOSS
OF YOUR RACHEL IN 1999.
I HOPE LIFE HAS BEEN MORE, I
DON'T KNOW, REDEMPTIVE -- I
DON'T EVEN KNOW THE WORD I
WANT.
HAS HELPED YOU HEAL.
TIME HAS HELPED YOU HEAL THIS
AWFUL WOUND BUT THANK YOU FOR
BEING WITH ME.
WHAT HAPPENED HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT WAS A GODLESS ACT,
REGARDLESS OF YOUR RELIGION,
OR YOUR LACK OF RELIGION.
WE ARE ALL UNITED IN OUR
DESIRE TO HEAL THE WOUNDS OF
THOSE WHO SUFFERED MOST.
EGREGIOUSLY HERE.
WE WILL TALK TO SOMEONE WHO IS
HELPING HEAL THOSE WOUNDS
AFTER THIS.
initiated.
Neural speeds
increasing to 4G LTE.
Brain upgrading to a quad-core
processor.
Predictive intelligence
with Google Now complete.
Introducing DROID DNA by HTC.
It's not an upgrade
to your phone.
It's an upgrade to yourself.
>> BACK LIVE HERE IN NEW TOWN
CONNECTICUT.
BEFORE I I MOVE TO THE BILLY
GRAHAM RAPID RESPONSE TEAM THE
MINISTERS, THE PASTORS WHO
HAVE COME TO COUNSEL THE
WOUNDED HERE, THE WOUNDED IN
TERMS OF THEIR SOULS BACK TO
MY LEGAL PANEL, ARTHUR AIDALA,
BO DIETL.
WHAT ABOUT MY PROPOSAL THAT
THERE BE AN ARMED COP AT EVERY
SCHOOL OVER A CERTAIN SIZE
REGARDLESS?
ARTHUR, YOU FIRST?
>> LOOK, GERALDO,
SEPTEMBER 11TH CHANGED THE WAY
WE FUNCTION AS A SOCIETY.
RIGHT?
I USED TO WALK INTO AN AIRPORT
AND 20 MINUTES BEFORE A FLIGHT
AND GO ON.
THIS PAST THURSDAY I HAD TO GO
TO FEDERAL COURT.
I'M A LAWYER.
I'M FINGERPRINTED.
I IS AN IDENTIFICATION CARD
WITH A HOLOGRAM.
I HAD TO TAKE EVERYTHING OFF.
I MEAN, I KEPT ON MY SHIRT AND
MY PANTS.
MY SHOES, MY BELT, MY COAT.
DO WE WANT OUR CHILDREN IN THE
FREEDOM OF THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA TO HAVE TO BE
SUBJECTED BECAUSE OF THE CRAZY
ACTS OF ONE LUNATIC THAT
HOPEFULLY THIS IS SOMETHING
THAT WILL HAPPEN FIRST IN A
CENTURY, NUPS A THAT LYNN YUM.
IT DOESN'T HAVE TO BE THAT
INTUNES AT A TWO DRAMATIC
THERE IS NO CRIME OTHER THAN
THAT WHY CAN'T HE SPENT THE
DAY WAITING OUTSIDE THE
SCHOOL.
>> GERALDO, YOU HAVE A LOT OF
YOUNG COPS RETIRING WITH 20
YEARS ON THE FORCE.
WE HAVE A LOT OF THEM THAT CAN
EFFECTIVELY BE TRAINED.
ARTHUR IS WRONG WOULD THEY
HAVE LIKED TO HAVE HAD SOMEONE
ARMED IN THAT SCHOOL THAT
COULD HAVE STOPPED THIS CREEP
FROM KILLING ALL THESE KIDS?
>> ONE CHILD, BUT WHAT I'M
SAYING IS YOU DO AN EFFECTIVE
THING AS FAR AS THE SCHOOL.
SAFETY EFFECTIVE AND YOU PUT
AN ARMED PINNER WITH A
CONCEALED WEAPON RETIREMENT
LAW ENFORCEMENT.
>> I DON'T THINK YOU CAN STOP
A MAD MAN, GERALDO.
LOOK, WHEN YOU HAVE AN ARMORED
HUMMER DRIVING OVER IN A WAR
ZONE AND HITS A LAND MIND,
THERE IS NO PROTECTION THERE.
THAT'S CRAZINESS, THAT'S WAR.
THIS IS SUCH A TERRIBLE
SITUATION THAT YOU CANNOT
PROTECT PEOPLE IN A SITUATION
LIKE THIS.
YOU HAVE TO GET TO THE
UNDERLYING ISSUE.
THAT'S MENTAL HEALTH, AND
THAT'S ALSO FAMILY VALUES.
REGARDLESS OF YOUR FAITH
GODLESS ACT THAT OCCURRED
HERE.
YOU HAVE TO INSERT GOD INTO
YOUR CONVERSATION.
JACK MONDAY IS A MASS TORE
WITH INTERNATIONAL DIRECTOR OF
THE WHOLE BILLY GRAM RAPID
RESPONSE TEAM.
FIRST, WHAT IS THAT PASTOR.
>> THE BILLY GRAHAM RESPONSE
TEAM IS A MINISTRY THAT
STARTED AFTER 9/11 TO COME
ALONGSIDE OF PEOPLE IN TIMES
LIKE THIS WHO HAVE BEEN
DEVASTATED WITH A CRISIS.
>> I KNOW YOU ARE WORKING WITH
THE VICTIMS OF HURRICANE SANDY
AND THEN YOU REROUTED MANY
PEOPLE UP HERE.
SO, YOU KNOW, HOW ARE YOU
CONSOLING THIS GRIEVOUS
INJURY?
>> WE MEET WITH THE EMERGENCY
MANAGER PEOPLE IN THE AREA
INTRODUCE OURSELF.
THEY HAVE BEEN GRACIOUS TO
ALLOW US TO WORK WITH THE
FIRST RESPONDERS AND THOSE IN
THE COMMUNITY.
WE HAVE BEEN SO GRATEFUL THAT
WE COULD BE HERE IN A
DIFFICULT TIME LIKE THIS.
>> IT IS WHEN PEOPLE GO
THROUGH TIMES LIKE THIS.
WE ALL ASKED THE GOD
QUESTIONS.
>> WHERE WAS GOD YESTERDAY?
>> WEIGHS RIGHT HERE.
HE WAS RIGHT HERE.
AND PEOPLE ARE EVIL.
HAVE EVIL ACTS.
AND WE HAVE FREE WILL.
AND HE HAS MADE US THAT WAY.
AND SO WE ARE HERE TO HELP
PEOPLE KNOW THAT GOD HASN'T
FOR GOTTEN THEM.
THAT HE LOVES THEM AND HE IS
HERE TO COMFORT THEM.
>> HOW IS REVEREND GRAHAM
RESPONDING TO THIS?
>> WELL, WITH GREAT SADNESS AS
WE ALL FROM.
-- ARE.
>> I'M SURE YOU ARE GIVING
COMFORT TO THESE PEOPLE WHO
ARE DESPERATELY IN NEED OF
COMFORTING DO YOU THINK SO THE
TIMING OF THIS MAKES IT MORE
EGREGIOUS THE FACT THAT IT IS
TWO WEEKS TO CHRISTMAS?
>> I BELIEVE IT IS.
THERE COULD BE CHRISTMAS TREES
RIGHT NOW THAT HAVE PRESENTS
UNDER THEM.
IT'S VERY DIFFICULT.
AND ESPECIALLY CHILDREN SO
YOUNG HEINOUS ACT.
PEOPLE ALL OVER THE WORLD ARE
PRAYING.
I'M GOING EMAILS FROM TEAMS IN
CANADA.
PEOPLE ARE PRAYING SO WE WON'T
FORGET THEM.
>> THANK YOU.
I'M SURE THEY WON'T FORGET THE
FACT THAT YOU ARE HERE.
THANK YOU.
THE DESPICABLE CRIME THAT
HAPPENED NEAR IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT WILL NEVER, SHOULD
NEVER BE EITHER FORGIVEN OR
FORGOTTEN IN MY VIEW.
THIS COMMUNITY, OUR COUNTRY,
WE HAVE TO HEAL EACH OTHER.
AS THE PRESIDENT SAID LAST
NIGHT, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
LET'S HOLD OUR CHILDREN A
LITTLE CLOSER.
LET'S BE AS COMPASSIONATE AND
AS GENEROUS AS WE POSSIBLY CAN
BE.
AS OUR OWN PERSONAL SITUATION
ALLOWS.
BE VIGILANT.
BE LOVING.
GENTLE, STRONG, GOOD NIGHT
FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
A TOWN WHOSE FALLEN CHILDREN
NOW BELONG TO THE AGES.
GOD BLESS THEM.
WE WILL SEE YOU AGAIN FOR A
SPECIAL EDITION OF THIS
PROGRAM TOMORROW NIGHT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR
LISTENING AND AS WE SEE THESE
NAMES, THESE YOUNG CHILDREN,
THE VICTIMS OF THE ATROCITY ON
YOUR SCREEN PRAY FOR THEM AND
THEIR FAMILIES.
GOOD NIGHT, EVERYBODY.
THANK YOU.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
Girl:
DON'T LOOK AT ME.
Second girl: YOUR HAIR'S
A BIT FRIZZY TODAY.
AW!
HA HA!
YOU SHOULD PICK
THAT UP.
Announcer: EVERY DAY,
KIDS WITNESS BULLYING.
POOR YOU. HA HA!
THEY WANT TO HELP
BUT DON'T KNOW HOW.
TEACH YOUR KIDS HOW TO BE
MORE THAN A BYSTANDER.
VISIT STOPBULLYING.GOV.