>> GOOD MORNING.
I AM HEATHER CHILDERS.
>> I AM PATTI ANN BROWNE.
IT IS TUESDAY DECEMBER 18TH.
THANK YOU FOR WATCHING "FOX &
FRIENDS FIRST".
>> ANOTHER EMOTIONAL DAY IN
NEWTOWN WHERE TWO MORE FUNERALS
WILL BE HELD TODAY FOR THE YOUNG
VICTIMS OF THE SANDY HOOK
TRAGEDY.
>> ONE IS FOR 6-YEAR-OLD JAMES
MAT.
>> THE OTHER IS FOR 6-YEAR-OLD
JESSICA REKOS.
SHE LOVED HORSES AND BEFRG HER
BROTHERS.
>> STHEY WILL HEAD BACK TO CLAS
FOR THE FIRST TIME AS POLICE
FIND OUT MORE ABOUT WHAT LED TO
THE SHOOTING.
>>> GOOD MORNING.
>> GOOD MORNING, PATTI ANN.
WE WERE STANDING UP THE STREET
OUTSIDE OF THE FIREHOUSE THAT IS
NEXT TO SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
IT IS THE SAME FIREHOUSE WHERE
STUDENTS ON FRIDAY SOUGHT REFUGE
FROM THE KILLER IN THEIR
CLASSROOM.
WE SAW MOVING TRUCKS THAT WERE
TAKING FURNITURE AND ARTWORK
FROM SANDY HOOK OVER TO CHALK
HILL ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEARBY
MONROE.
IT IS WHERE THE STUDENTS OF
SANDY HOOK ARE GOING TO GO BACK
TO SCHOOL WHEN IT IS FINALLY
TIME.
THREES NO DATE LEFT BUT THE IDEA
IS TO TRY TO MAKE THE TRANSITION
HARSH.E OF THE SHELL SHOCKED
>> THE SANDY HOOK SCHOOL
FURNITURE WILL BE MOVED DOWN SO
IT WILL BE AGE AND HEIGHT
APPROPRIATE.
THE HEALING AND BACK TO NORMALCY
FEELING THAT WILL HOPEFULLY COME
FROM IT.
>>> AS PER THE LATEST ON THE
INVESTIGATION AUTHORITIES
REVEALED YESTERDAY TWO SURVIVING
ADULTS ARE RECOVERING FROM GUN
SHOT WOUNDS TO THEIR LOWER
EXTREMITIES.
WE KNEW THEY WERE RECOVERING
FROM GUN SHOT WOUNDS WE DIDN'T
KNOW WHERE THE WOUNDS FROM.
WE KNOW THEY ARE SOMEWHERE IN
THE LOWER EXTREMITIES.
THEY ARE NOT ONLY RECOVERING BUT
THEY ARE TALKING TO AUTHORITIES
GIVING THEM THE STORY HELPING
THEM PIECE TOGETHER WHAT
HAPPENED INSIDE THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL ON FRIDAY.
WE ARE HEARING MORE ABOUT THE
SHOOTER ADAM LANZA AND HIS
MOTHER NANCY FROM THEIR FRIENDS.
>> SHE HAS BEEN DESCRIBED AS
SOME SORT OF GUN ENTHUSIASTS,
GUN SURVIVALIST AND THINGS THAT
I HAVE HEARD.
THAT'S NOT THE NANCY I KNOW.
>> IF NANCY WAS WITH US STILL
THE DEVASTATION SHE WOULD HAVE
OF WHAT HER OWN CHILD DID TO
THESE OTHER, THESE LITTLE
BABIES, I CAN'T REALLY TALK
ABOUT THE BABIES.
>> THERE ARE A LOT OF THINGS
HERE IN NEWTOWN, CHRISTMAS
DECORATIONS THAT WERE PUT UP
BEFORE FRIDAY'S MASS MURDERERS
OF THE STREET.
THEY ARE ALSO HERE BUT IT SEEMS
LIKE IT IS REALLY HARD FOR FOLKS
IN THIS AREA TO GET INTO THE
SPIRIT OF THE HOLIDAYS.
CHRISTMAS ONE WEEK FROM TODAY
WHEN FOR EXAMPLE THE CHRISTMAS
TREE BEHIND ME IS SURROUNDED BY
TRIBUTES TO THE 26 PEOPLE WHO
DIED IN THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
ABOUT A QUARTER MILE AWAY.
>> FAMILY FRIENDS AND RESIDENTS
OF NEW TOWN CONNECTICUT SAYING
THEIR FINAL FAREWELLS AND TWO OF
THE SCHOOL SHOOTING VICTIMS LAID
TO REST WEDNESDAY.
>> WHITE BALLOONS LINING THE
BLOCK OUTSIDE OF ONE FUNERAL
HOME IN FAIRFIELD CONNECTICUT.
A BIM BOLL OF PURITY A TRIBUTE
OF A LIFE BEING REMEMBERED
INSIDE THE FUNERAL HOME.
THE YOUNGEST VICTIM 6-YEAR-OLD
NOAH POZNER WHO LIKED ANIMALS
VIDEO AND MEXICAN FOOD.
HE USED TO TELL PEOPLE HE WORKED
IN A TACO FACTORY.
>> HE WAS A PURE INNOCENT CHILD
THE PROMISE OF LIFE AHEAD OF HIM
WHO BROUGHT JOY TO HIS FAMILY
AND TO HIS COMMUNITY AND WILL BE
SORELY MISSED.
AS HIS OLDER BROTHER SAID HE
COULD HAVE BEEN ANYTHING.
>> HE LEAVES BEHIND TWO SIBLINGS
INTERESTING HIS SISTER WHO HE
CONSIDERS HIS BEST FRIEND.
>> 6-YEAR-OLD JACK PINTO WAS A
HUGE SPORTS FAN.
HE JUST JOINED THE COMMUNITY
WREST {SUFFIXÑ]LI
WRESTLING TEAM.
THEY BURIED HIM IN HIS NEW YORK
GIANT PLAYER VICTOR CRUZ.
>> THE COLLEGE ROOMMATE OF
TEACHER VICTORIA SOTO WILL
ALWAYS REMEMBER HER BEST
FRIEND'S AMAZING SACRIFICE.
SOTO USED HER BODY TO SHIELD THE
FIRST GRADERS FROM THE GUNMAN.
>> SHE LOVED HER JOB AND SHE
LOVED THEM.
I WAS NOT AT ALL SURPRISED THAT
SHE WOULD DO THIS THAT SHE WOULD
PROTECT THEM AND GIVE HER LIFE
TO SAVE THEIRS.
HEARTBREAKING BUT I KNEW THAT'S
WHAT SHE WOULD DO.
THESE KIDS WERE HER LIFE.
>> SOTO WILL BE LAID TO REST
TOMORROW.
>>> ANOTHER TOUGH DAY MANY MORE
TO COME.
THANK YOU SO MUCH, AINSLEY.
>>> IT IS TIME NOW FOR YOUR
5@5:00.
THE TOP FIVE MAKING NEWS AT THIS
HOUR.
HE REPRESENTED HAWAII FROM THE
TIME IT BECAME A STATE IN 1959.
THE NATION NOW MOURNING THE LOSS
OF DEMOCRATIC SENATOR DANIEL
IN
INOUYE.
>> HE RARELY CALLED ATTENTION TO
HIMSELF.
BUT TO LIVED A REMARKABLE LIFE
FILLED WITH DIGNITY AND GRACE OF
THE TRUE HERO HE WAS.
>> PRO-TEM INAWDIANA N-- INOUYES
88 YEARS OLD.
>> THE BENGHAZI TERROR ATTACK IS
IN THE HANDS OF SECRETARY OF
STATE HILLARY CLINTON.
IT COULD REVEAL MYTH OR IGNORE
WARNING SIGNS BEFORE THE ATTACK
WHICH LEFT FOUR AMERICANS DEAD.
THE LEADERS WILL BRIEF LAWMAKER
RS TOMORROW.
CLINTON NO LONGER TESTIFYING
BEFORE CONGRESS THIS WEEK AFTER
CONCUSSIONS.
JOHN BOLTON SAYS CLINTON STILL
MUST TESTIFY.
>> WHEN YOU DON'T WANT TO GO TO
A MEETING OR CONFERENCE OR EVENT
YOU HAVE A DIPLOMATIC ILLNESS.
THIS IS A DIPLOMATIC ILLNESS TO
BEAT THE BAND.
SHE MAY BE TESTIAT TESTIFYING T
WEEK BUT SHE IS NOT GOING TO
ESCAPE THIS FOREVER.
>> THE STATE DEPARTMENT SAYS
CLINTON SUFFERED A CONCUSSION
AFTER FAINTING.
>> SHE IS THE RIGHT U.S. SENATOR
FOR HER STATE AND HER COUNTRY.
SOUTH CAROLINA GOVERNOR NIKKI
HALEY PICKING TIM SCOTT TO
REPLACE OUTGOING SENATOR JIM
DEMINT.
SCOTT VOWING TO CONTINUE
FOCUSING ON OUR COUNTRY'S
SOARING DEBT.
>> NO MATTER HOW MUCH WE
INCREASE TAXES IT WILL NOT HAVE
A DINT ON THE DEFICIT.
FOR US TO CLOSE THE GAP WE ARE
GOING TO HAVE TO HAVE A SERIOUS
DISCUSSION ABOUT SPENDING
REFORM.
>>> SCOTT WILL BECOME THE FIST
BLACK SENATOR FROM LINE GNAW.
HE WILL HAVE TO RUN AGAIN FOR
2014.
>> HE WILL BE HOME FOR
CHRISTMAS.
FORMER PRESIDENT GEORGE H.W.
BUSH EXPECTED TO BE RELEASED
FROM THE HOSPITAL IN THE NEXT
WEEK.
THE 41ST PRESIDENT IS BEING
TREATED FOR A BRONCHITIS RELATED
COUGH.
HE HAS BEEN IN THE HOSPITAL
SINCE NOVEMBER 23RDRD.
BUT DOCTORS SAY HE IS CONTINUING
TO MAKE PROGRESS.
>>> ONE OF OUR NATION'S WOUNDED
WARRIORS WILL BE HAVING AN EXTRA
SPECIAL CHRISTMAS THIS YEAR.
HE WILL FINALLY BE ABLE TO WALK
ON HIS OWN AGAIN.
LAST CHRISTMAS DAY CORPORAL WAS
HIT WITH AN I EASTBOUNDING D AND
LOST ONE OF HIS LEGS.
THIS YEAR HE'S LEARNING TO USE
HIS BRAND NEW PROSTHETIC LEG.
>>> A YEAR AFTER YOU GET INJURED
OR WHATEVER HAPPENS AND THAT'S
REALLY THE WAY IT IS ON
CHRISTMAS THE DATE I GOT
INJURED.
>> HIS BIGGEST CHALLENGE IS
KEEPING UP WITH HIS 1-YEAR-OLD
SON.
THAT'S YOUR 5@5:00.
>>> WE MAY BE INCHING, MAYBE,
TOWARDS A BILL TO AVOID THE
SO-CALLED FISCAL CLIFF.
BOTH SIDES SAY PROGRESS IS BEING
MADE AND THE PRESIDENT MAY BE
MAKING SOME CONFESSIONS.
KEL REWRIGHT LIVE IN WASHINGTON
WITH MORE ON WHAT THAT MAY BE.
>> SPEAKER OF THE HOUSE JOHN
BOEHNER MET WITH THE PRESIDENT
ON MONDAY.
THE TWO DISCUSSED WHAT THEY CAN
DO TO AVOID THE FISCAL CLIFF.
MR. FWHIER P BY ANOTHER PUT TH
BEFORE THE PRESIDENT.
IN A COUNTEROFFER THE PRESIDENT
PROPOSED TO RAISE TAXES ON THOSE
MAKING 400,000 A YEAR.
>> IN ORDER TO ACHIEVE A BROAD
DEFICIT REDUCTION PACKAGE THAT
PUTS OUR ECONOMY ON A
SUSTAINABLE FISCAL PATH IN THE
FUTURE A CERTAIN LEVEL OF
REVENUE CLEANED FROM THE WEALTHY
HAS TO BE MET.
THE ONLY WAY TO DO THAT WAS
THROUGH -- IN PART RATES RISING.
>> A ROUGH OUTLINE OF THE DEAL
CALLS FOR 1 TRILLION IN CUTS,
ONE TRILLION IN REVENUE,
IMMEDIATE DOWN PAYMENT AND
LEGISLATIVE PROCESS THROUGH NEXT
YEAR.
IN THE PREVIOUS MEETING THE TWO
SIDES REMAIN PFAR APART ON
AGREEMENT.
NOW THEY APPEAR TO BE SOME WHAT
CLOSER TO A DEAL.
PRESIDENT OBAMA PROPOSED SOME OF
THE DEMANDS ON SPENDING CUTS ON
ENTITLEMENT PROGRAM SUCH AS
CURTAILING FUTURE INFLATION
ADJUST AMS FOR FUTURE RECIPIENTS
OF SOCIAL SECURITY.
MICHAEL STEELE SAYS ANY MOVEMENT
AWAY FROM THE UNREALISTIC OFFER
THE PRESIDENT HAS MADE
PREVIOUSLY IS A STEP IN THE
RIGHT DIRECTION.
PROPOSAL THAT INCLUDES
1.2 TRILLION IN REVENUE FOR ONLY
930 BILLION IN SPENDING CUTS
CANNOT BE CONSIDERED BALANCED.
WE HAVE TO REACH AN AGREEMENT
THAT IS TRULY BALANCED AND BEGAN
TO SMALL OR SPENDING PROBLEM.
>>> THEY HAVE TWO WEEKS TO GET A
DEAL BEFORE THE AUTOMATIC CUTS
GO INTO EFFECT.
HARRY REID SAYS IT APPEARS THE
SENATE MAY BE COMING BACK THE
DAY AFTER CHRISTMAS TO DEAL WITH
AVERTING THE FISCAL CLIFF.
>> WE ARE ALL EYEING THAT CLOCK
RIGHT THERE BESIDE.
YOU THANK YOU VERY MUCH, KELLY.
>> IT IS TIME FOR YOUR FIRST
DEGREE WEATHER UPDATE WITH MARIA
MOLINA.
MARIA, THINGS WARMING UP A
LITTLE BIT TODAY?
>> PATTI ANN AND HEATHER GOOD TO
SEE YOU.
WE ARE GOING TO BE SEEING
TEMPERATURES ABOVE AVERAGE
ACROSS PORTIONS OF THE COUNTRY.
COOL SIDE IN DALLAS 41 DEGREES
OUT THERE 44 KANSAS CITY.
AS WE CONTINUE OUR TRACK
NORTHWARD LITTLE ON THE CHILLY
SIDE MINNEAPOLIS 23 DEGREES 45
IN NEW YORK CITY.
NEW YORK CITY WE HAD TO DEAL
WITH A LOT OF HEAVY RAIN LAST
NIGHT AND THROUGH OUT THE
OVERNIGHT HOURS.
THE WORST OF IT HAS MOVED
NORTHWARD.
WE HAVE HEAVIER RAIN ACROSS NEW
ENGLAND.
HIGH TEMPERATURE IN NEW YORK
CITY SUNSHINE 51 DEGREES.
70s WIDESPREAD.
UPPER 70s ACROSS THE STATE OF
TEXAS ABOVE AVERAGE HERE'S A
QUICK SHOT OF THE RAINFALL OVER
NEW ENGLAND NORTHERN PARTS OF
MAINE COULD PICK UP MORE THAN 6
INCHES OF SNOW IN SOME OF THE
HIGHER ELEVATIONS.
>> IN TIME FOR CHRISTMAS.
>> WHITE CHRISTMAS.
>> AND THE TIME RIGHT NOW 12
AFTER THE HOUR.
STILL TO COME IN A FEW DAYS
MILLIONS OF PEOPLE WILL HIT THE
ROADS FOR THE HOLIDAYS AND THEY
MAY BE GETTING AN EARLY
CHRISTMAS PRESENT.
>> THIS MOTHER OF TWO WALKING
OUT OF THE HOSPITAL AS A MEDICAL
MIRACLE.
SHE RECEIVED NOT ONE, NOT TWO,
BUT THREE ORGAN TRANSPLANTS.
and it's so rich
and creamy...
is it really 100 calories?
Let me put you on webcan...
...lean roasted chicken...
and a creamy broth
Mmm
I can still see you.
[ Male announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
MATTIOLI.
>> 15 AFTER THE HOUR.
THE MAN ACCUSED OF KILLING TWO
POLICE OFFICERS IN TOPEKA KANSAS
HAS DIED.
AFTER A TWO-HOUR LONG STANDOFF
THEY USED TEAR GAS TO GET HIM
OUT OF THE HOME.
WHEN HE RAN OUT HE WAS CARRYING
A GUN AND HE WAS SHOT.
IT'S NOT KNOWN IF HE FIRED ANY
SHOTS.
AN OHIO KILLER WHO ARGUED HE WAS
TOO FAT TO BE PUT TO DEATH WILL
NOW SPEND THE REST OF HIS LIFE
IN PRISON WITHOUT PAROLE.
RONALD POST WAS GRANTED CLEMENCY
NOT FOR HIS WEIGHT BUT BECAUSE
HE HAD POOR LEGAL
REPRESENTATION.
HE WAS CONVICTED OF KILLING A
HOTEL CLERK IN 1963.
>> NOW TO STORIES YOU CAN BANK
ON THIS MORNING AFTER ONLY A
YEAR AT THE TOP GENERAL MOTORS
LOSING IT'S TITLE AS THE WORLD'S
LARGEST AUTO MAKER TO TOYOTA.
WE TURN TO LAUREN SIMONETTI FROM
THE FOX BUSINESS NETWORK.
>> THEY ARE SET TO RECLAIM THE
STATUS AS THE WORLD'S LARGEST
AUTO MAKER.
IT WILL LOST THAT TITLE LAST
YEAR AFTER THE TSUNAMI IN JAPAN.
GENERAL MOTORS MAY NOT MOVE TO
SECOND PLACE MAYBE INTO THIRD
PLACE BECAUSE VOGUES WAGON SALES
ARE ON FIRE.
IT WILL TAKE THE TOP SPOT BY THE
YEAR 2018 INCH ALL THEY ARE
HEADED FOR A RECORD SALES YEAR.
SALE ALSO TOP 80 MILLION THROUGH
OUT YEAR.
>> LOW GAS PRICES.
>> THIS IS THE LOWEST OF THE
YEAR AT THIS POINT.
IT IS GREAT NEWS FOR THE DRIVERS
EXPECTED TO HIT THE ROAD THIS
WEEKEND.
COMBAS PRICES $3.34 A GALLON.
WHAT IS MORE IT WILL BE LESS IF
WE FALL OFF THE FISCAL CLIFF.
>> THE SCANNERS YOU HAVE TO GO
THROUGH AT THE AIRPORT WE MADE A
GOOD CONNECTION.
>> THEY WILL GO THROUGH THE
ADVANCED AIRPORT RECORD MACHINE.
THEY OTT NOBLE REQUIRE AN
INDEPENDENT STUDY OF THE X-RAY
SCANNER BUT ALSO LET TRAVELERS
KNOW THEY HAVE OTHER SCREENING
OPTIONS.
PREGNANT WOMEN ARE MORE
SENSITIVE TO THE RADIATION
EXPOSURE.
>> LAUREN SIMONETTI AS ALWAYS WE
APPRECIATE IT.
>> THE TIME IS 18 AFTER THE TOP
OF THE HOUR.
COMING UP NEXT ON THE RUNDOWN
FOR YOU KEY OBAMA CARE
REGULATIONS ABOUT TO GO IN PLACE
WITHOUT THE NORMAL 60 DAY
COMMENT PERIOD.
IS THE ADMINISTRATION TRYING TO
QUIETLY FAST TRACK SOME OF THESE
ITEMS?
THEN FLY TO GO THE HOLIDAY
DESTINATION YOU BETTER PACK THE
HAND SAN TIRES.
A LOOK AT SOME OF THE GERM HOT
SPOTS AND ON BOARD THE PLANE.
..
AND ALONG WITH IT,
MORE IDENTITY THEFT.
BY THE TIME THIS HOLIDAY SEASON
IS OVER, AN ESTIMATED
1.2 MILLION IDENTITIES
MAY BE STOLEN.
EVERY TIME YOU PULL OUT YOUR
WALLET, SHOP ONLINE OR HIT THE
ROAD, YOU GIVE THIEVES A CHANCE
TO RUIN YOUR HOLIDAY.
BY THE TIME YOU'RE DONE WATCHING
THIS, AS MANY AS 40 MORE
IDENTITIES MAY BE STOLEN.
YOU CAN'T BE ON THE LOOKOUT
24/7, BUT LIFELOCK CAN.
THEY'RE RELENTLESS ABOUT
PROTECTING YOUR IDENTITY
EVERY MINUTE OF EVERY DAY.
WHEN SOMEONE TRIES TO TAKE OVER
YOUR BANK ACCOUNTS, DRAIN THE
EQUITY IN YOUR HOME, OR EVEN
TRIES TO BUY A CAR IN YOUR NAME,
LIFELOCK IS ON GUARD.
AND WITH LIFELOCK'S 24/7 ALERTS,
THEY CONTACT YOU BY TEXT,
PHONE OR EMAIL AS SOON AS THEY
DETECT SUSPICIOUS ACTIVITY
IN THEIR NETWORK.
LIFELOCK WANTS YOU TO BE
PROTECTED THIS HOLIDAY SEASON,
SO THEY'RE GIVING YOU 60 DAYS
OF PROTECTION RISK-FREE.
>> MY YEARS AS A PROSECUTOR
TAUGHT ME THAT YOU HAVE TO BE
PROACTIVE TO PROTECT YOURSELF
FROM CRIME,
AND THAT'S ESPECIALLY TRUE
OF IDENTITY THEFT.
THAT'S WHY I'M A MEMBER
OF LIFELOCK.
>> Announcer: ABSOLUTELY NO ONE
PROTECTS YOU BETTER THAN
LIFELOCK, AND THEY STAND BEHIND
THEIR PROTECTION WITH THE POWER
OF THEIR $1 MILLION
SERVICE GUARANTEE.
IN FACT, LAST YEAR, LIFELOCK
PROTECTED OVER TWO MILLION
PEOPLE DURING THE HOLIDAYS.
AND NOW THEY CAN DO IT FOR YOU.
TRY LIFELOCK'S PROTECTION
60 DAYS RISK-FREE.
CALL THE NUMBER ON YOUR SCREEN
OR GO TO LIFELOCK.COM/HOLIDAYS.
IT ONLY TAKES MINUTES
TO SIGN UP.
USE PROMO CODE: HOLIDAYS.
ORDER NOW AND GET A SPECIAL
HOLIDAY GIFT: A DOCUMENT
SHREDDER TO KEEP SENSITIVE
DOCUMENTS OUT OF THE WRONG
HANDS... A $29 VALUE, FREE!
CALL THE NUMBER ON YOUR SCREEN
OR GO ONLINE AND LET LIFELOCK
PROTECT YOUR IDENTITY FOR
60 DAYS RISK-FREE.
BECAUSE DURING THE HOLIDAYS,
KEEPING YOUR IDENTITY PROTECTED
MEANS KEEPING YOUR
FAMILY PROTECTED.
>> WELCOME BACK.
IT IS 22 AFTER THE TOP OF THE
HOUR.
22 MEMBERS OF PIE CAP PAW ALPHA
FACING HAZING CHARGES AFTER A
PLEDGE DIED LAST MONTH IN THEIR
FRATERNITY HOUSE.
HIS BLOOD ALCOHOL LEVEL WAS
ABOUT 5 TIMES THE LEGAL LIMIT
FOR DRIVING.
THIS 38-YEAR-OLD SURVIVED A
TRIPLE ORGAN TRANSPLANT FOR HER
HEART, LIVER AND KIDNEY.
THERE HAS ONLY BEEN 6 PERFORMED
IN THE PAST FOUR YEARS.
SHE WILL BE ON FOX AND FRIENDS
TO SHARE HER INCREDIBLE STORY.
>> IF YOU ARE TRAVELING DURING
THE HOLIDAYS YOU WON'T BE ALONE
ACCORDING TO TRIPLE A.
93 MILLION AMERICANS WILL BE AT
HOME.
DR. IS FROM WINTHROP UNIVERSITY
HOSPITAL.
AS A CHECKPOINT PEOPLE TAKE OFF
SHOES NOT WEARING SOCKS.
>> THE PROBLEM WITH AIRPORTS IS
YOU HAVE MANY PEOPLE
PARTICULARLY ON AIRPLANES IN A
SMALL AREA.
IN 2007 THEY FOUND THESE ARE
WASHED AS OFTEN AS -- AS LITTLE
AS EVERY 30-DAYS.
>> THIS WAS PUBLISHED IN THE
WALL STREET JOURNAL IN 2007 THIS
IS BEFORE THEY WERE WASHING
PLAIN KETS AND PUTTING THEM
INSIDE.
IT IS A CONCERN FOR SOME
AIRLINES THAT STILL DON'T WASH
THEIR BLANKETS.
>> THE BILL LOWS YOU SHOULD P--
PILLOWS YOU SHOULD PUT A
SWEATSHIRT OR SOMETHING OVER IT.
>> LATCHES ON OVER HEAD BINS.
GERM HOT SPOTS.
>> THE STUDIES TV SCREENS, BUT
PARTICULARLY THE LAST ON OVER
HEAD BINS MAKING FRIENDS THAT
HAVE NOROVIRUS THESE ARE KEY
AREAS THAT THEY ARE LOOKING AT
ALL OF THE TIME.
>> WIPE IT DOWN.
VL ANTIBACTERIAL.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
THE KEY IS TO A HEALTHY IMMUNE
SYSTEM.
POOR DIET LACK OF SLEEP WILL
EFFECT THE IMMUNE SYSTEM.
TAKE WATER ON THE PLAIN WE KNOW
DEHYDRATION WILL EFFECT YOU.
AN INGREDIENT THAT CAN FIX YOUR
SYSTEM.
GET A FLU SHOT BEFORE YOU
TRAVEL.
>> YOU CAN DO OTHER THINGS TO
WIPE DOWN THE SURFACES AND
PROTECT YOUR GIRLS.
THE AIR IS RECIRCULATED.
>> YOU CAN SAY STAY WELL
HYDRATED BEFORE YOU GET ON THE
PLANE.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR JOINING
US.
>> AND THE TIME RIGHT NOW 25
MINUTES AFTER THE HOUR.
STILL TO COME A GROUP OF PARENTS
THREATENING TO SUE OVER THIS
SONG.
♪
>> THEY SAY THIS AND OTHER
CHRISTMAS CAROLS ARE BULLYING.
PLUS THE EASY BAKE OVEN ABOUT TO
GET A MAKE-OVER WITH ONE LITTLE
GIRL WHO TOOK ON A BIG COMPANY
AND WON.
how does it work?
You just he to eat it as part
of your heart healthy diet.
Step 1. Eat the soup.
All those
veggies and beans,
that's what may help
lower your cholesterol and --
Well that's easy
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
>> WELCOME BACK TO "FOX &
FRIENDS FIRST".
I AM PATTI ANN BROWNE.
>> I AM HEATHER CHILDERS.
IT IS A SECOND DAY OF GOOD-BYES
IN NEWTOWN TODAY AS TWO MORE
YOUNG VICTIMS OF THE SANDY HOOK
TRAGEDY ARE LAID TO REST.
>> ONE IS FOR 6-YEAR-OLD JAMES
MATTIOLI CALLED JAY.
HE LOVED RECESS AND MATH.
THEY CALLED HIM THEIR NUMBERS
GUY.
JESSICA REKOS WHO LOVED
EVERYTHING ABOUT HORSES AND
PLAYING WITH HER LITTLE BROTHER.
>> STUDENTS AT OTHER NEWTOWN
SCHOOLS WILL HEAD BACK TO CLASS
FOR THE FIRST TIME AS THEY LEARN
MORE ABOUT WHAT LED TO THE
SHOOTING.
PETER DOSY JO
PETER DOOCY JOINS US LIVE.
>> LAST NIGHT MOVING TRUCKS
COMPLETE WITH THEIR OWN POLICE
HE IS COURTS WERE TAKING
FURNITURE OUT OF THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THEY WERE DRIVING DOWN PAST THE
FIREHOUSE WHICH IS WHERE
STUDENTS WERE LUCKY ENOUGH TO
GET OUT.
INCLUDING SOME 26 CHRISTMAS
TREES TO THE FALLEN STUDENTS.
THEY WERE TAKING THAT FURNITURE
TO NEARBY CHALK HILLS MIDDLE
SCHOOL AN UNOCCUPIED SCHOOL
BUILDING IN MONROE.
IT IS UNOCCUPIED BECAUSE OF LOW
ENROLLMENT.
THAT IS THE BUILDING WHERE SANDY
HOOK STUDENTS WILL GO BACK TO
CLASS WHEN THE STUDENTS DECIDE
IT IS THE RIGHT TIME.
THE REASON THEY ARE BRINGING ALL
OF THAT FURNITURE AND ARTWORK
FROM THE SCHOOL WHICH IS THE
SITE FROM A TERRIBLE CRIME IS
WHEN CLASSES START AGAIN THE
TRANSITION WON'T BE AS AGRACIVE.
>> THE SANDY HOOK STUDIO WILL BE
DOWN BECAUSE OF WAIJ HEIGHT AND
AGE APPROPRIATE.
IT IS AN ENORMOUS PROCESS.
THE HEALING AND BACK TO NORMALCY
FEELING THAT WILL COME FROM IT
HOPEFULLY IS WORTH EVERY EFFORT.
>>> AS FOR THE LATEST IN THE
INVESTIGATION WE LEARN THAT THE
TWO ADULTS WHO SURVIVED THE
SHOOTING HAVE GUN SHOT WOUNDS TO
THEIR LOWER EXTREMITIES.
WE ALSO LEARN THAT AUTHORITIES
HAVE NO CONTACT WITH ADAM LANZA
THE MURDERER BEFORE FRIDAY.
IF HE HAD SOME KIND OF A
CRIMINAL BACKGROUND THE
AUTHORITIES DID NOT KNOW ABOUT
IT THEY STILL DID NOT KNOW ABOUT
IT.
AT LEAST THEY HAVE NOT TOLD US
THEY DO.
HE POLLUTED THE EDUCATION WENT
ABOVE AND BEYOND THE CALL OF
DUTY FOR HIS STUDENTS.
>> THOHE GAVE THEIR LIVES SO OTS
COULD LIVE.
THERE ARE THOSE TEACHERS IN A
CALM QUICK THINKING ACTION SAVED
MANY LIVES THEY ARE HEROS ALSO.
I WAS WALKING AROUND TO SEE WHAT
WAS GOING ON.
THERE ARE MANY DOZENS OF PEOPLE
COMING TO LAY FLOWERS OR LEAVE
STUFFED ANIMALS AT ONE OF THE
MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS LIKE ONE AT
THE CHRISTMAS TREE.
IT'S A CHRISTMAS TREE
BEAUTIFULLY DECORATED YOU KNOW
ON THE CALENDAR NEXT WEEK IS
CHRISTMAS BUT REALLY YOU DON'T
GET A SENSE WALKING THROUGH A
TOWN THAT HAS BEEN SO DEVASTATED
WITH MANY PEOPLE COMING TO PAY
THEIR RESPECTS BASICALLY COMING
AND WALKING AROUND IN COMPLETE
SILENCE YOU DON'T GET A SENSE
THAT PEOPLE ARE HAVING AN EASY
TIME COMING INTO THE SPIRIT AND
YOU WONDER IF THEY WILL.
>> LIVE FAPLY AND FRIENDS SAYING
THEIR FINAL FAREWELL.
TWO OF THE SHOOTING VICTIMS ARE
LAID TO REST.
>>> WHITE BALLOONS LINING THE
BLOCK OUTSIDE OF ONE FUNERAL
HOME.
A TRIBUTE OF THE LIFE BEING
REMEMBERED INSIDE.
THE YOUNGEST VICTIM 6-YEAR-OLD
NOAH POZNER WHO WAS REMEMBERED
AS A BOY WHO LIKED ANIMALS VIDEO
AND MEXICAN FOOD.
HE USED TO TELL PEOPLE HE WORKED
IN A TACO FACTORY.
>> HE WAS CELEBRATED AS A PURE,
INNOCENT CHILD LIKE THE PROMISE
OF LIFE AHEAD OF HIM WHO BROUGHT
JOY TO HIS FAMILY AND TO HIS
COMMUNITY AND WILL BE SORELY
MISSED AND AS HIS OLDER BROTHER
SAID HE COULD HAVE BEEN ANYTHING
AS HE WOULD HAVE GROWN OLDER.
>> NOAH LEAVES BEHIND TWOUR
SIBLINGS INCLUDING A TWIN SISTER
WHO HE CONSIDERED HIS BEST
FRIEND.
SHE DID SURVIVE THAT SHOOTING.
>> A FEW MILES AWAY ANOTHER
FUNERAL TOOK PLACE.
6-YEAR-OLD JACK PINTO WAS A HUGE
SPORTS FAN WHO JUST JOINED A
WRESTLING TEAM.
HE WAS BURIED IN CRUZ' JERSEY.
CRUZ HONORED THE LITTLE BOY BY
WEARING HIS NAME ON HIS CLEATS.
VICTORIA SOTO'S FRIENDS WILL
ALWAYS REMEMBER HER AMAZING
SACRIFICE.
SOTO USED HER BODY TO SHIELD THE
FIRST GRADERS FROM THE GUNMEN.
>> SHE LOVED HER JOB AND LOVED
THEM I AM NOT AT ALL SURPRISED
SHE WOULD DO THIS PROTECT THEM
AND GIVE HER LIFE TO SAVE
THEIRS.
I KNEW THAT'S WHAT SHE WOULD DO.
THESE KIDS WERE HER LIFE.
>> SOTO WILL BE LAID TO REST
TOMORROW.
>>> PATTI ANN, BACK TO YOU.
>> NOW FOR YOUR 5@5:30.
THE TOP FIVE STORIES MAKING NEWS
AT THIS HOUR.
IT HAS BEEN AN ONGOING
INVESTIGATION FOR NEARLY A YEAR.
WHO LEAKED CLASSIFIED
INFORMATION FOR THE MOVIE ABOUT
THE HUNT FOR OSAMA BIN LADEN.
>> OSAMA BIN LADEN.
(INAUDIBLE)
>> THERE MAY BE ANSWERS ABOUT
THE MOVIE DARK 30.
REPORTS SAY MIEBLG VISHINGS THE
UNDER SECRETARY OF DEFENSE FOR
INTELLIGENCE GAVE THE RESTRICTED
INFO TO FILM AMERICAS.
THE JUSTICE DEPARTMENT RECEIVED
THE CASE BUT HAS DECLINED TO
PROSECUTE.
VICKERS HAS BEEN MENTIONED AS
THE NEXT CANDIDATE TO BE THE
NEXT CIA DIRECTOR.
>> WE ARE SEEING THE FIRST PHOTO
OF A MARINE WHO HAS BEEN LOCKED
UP FOUR MONTHS AGO.
HE WAS SEEN WITH CHAINS AROUND
HIS ANKLES.
IT WAS SENT TO HIS FAMILY.
HE WAS ARRESTED TRYING TO
DECLARE AN ANTIQUE SHOT GUN AT
THE BORDER.
HE WAS CARRYING WHAT OFFICIALS
SAY WAS AN ILLEGAL WEAPON.
HIS MOM WILL BE ON FOX AND
FRIENDS AT 8:20 EASTERN THIS
MORNING.
>>> AMERICANS FOR LIMITED
GOVERNMENT AND OTHER WATCH DOG
GROUPS ARE OUTRAGED OVER
REGULATIONS THAT DO NOT MEET
COMMENT PERIOD.
60 DAYS ARE THE MINIMUM THAT
THREE OF THE REGULATIONS HAVE A
30-DAY COMMENT PERIOD AND ONE 24
DAYS.
THE REGULATIONS ARE BEING BURIED
DURING THE HOLIDAYS IN A TIME
WHEN LAWMAKERS ARE FOCUSED ON
THAT FISCAL CLIFF.
>> DOES THIS SONG SOUND LIKE A
FORM OF BULLY TO GO YOU?
>> A GROUP OF PARENTS IN MONTANA
ARGUE THAT THEY ARE OUTRAGED
OVER THE CHRISTMAS CAROLS BEING
SUNG AT A RECENT SCHOOL CONCERT
AND ARE THREATENING TO SUE THE
DISTRICT UNLESS YOI TO THE WORLD
IS REPLACED WITH FROSTY THE
SNOWMAN.
THEY CLAIM SONGS THAT REFER TO
THE LORD ARE UNFAIR AND
UNCONSTITUTIONAL.
>> A NEW JERSEY TEAM CAMPAIGNING
FOR AN EASY BAKE OVEN FOR BOYS
IS GETTING HER WISH AFTER
MEETING WITH 13-YEAR-OLD MEK
KENNA POST MONDAY HASBRO HAS
MADE A GENDER NEUTRAL BLACK AND
SILVER MODEL NEXT YEAR.
POST STARTED THE CAMPAIGN SO SHE
COULD BUY ONE FOR HER LITTLE
BROTHER.
HER ON L RECEIVED
44,000 SIGNATURES AND SUPPORT OF
BOBBY FLAY.
>> GOOD IDEA.
>> THAT IS YOUR 5@5:30.
>> IT MAY BE BABY STEPS BUT
DEMOCRATS AND REPUBLICANS ARE
BOTH SIGNALING PROGRESS AND
TALKS TO AVOID THE SO-CALLED
FISCAL CLIFF.
DOUG LUZADER HAS MORE ON THIS.
>>> GOOD MORNING GUYS.
THESE TWO GUYS MAY BE MOVING
CLOSER TO ONE ANOTHER ON A DEAL
NOR MASSIVE TAX HIKES.
HE IS TELLING FELLOW REPUBLICANS
HE IS NOT GIVING AWAY TOO MUCH
IN THE PROCESS.
WE SAW THE SPEAKER RETURN TO THE
CAPITAL AFTER ANOTHER
NEGOTIATING SESSION FROM THE
WHITE HOUSE.
HE DIDN'T LOOK ALL THAT PLEASED.
IT WAS A TAX HIKE ON THOSE
MAKING 200,000 A YEAR.
IT IS UP FROM THE 250,000 HE WAS
SEEKING.
>>> PARAMETERS OF THE POTENTIAL
AGREEMENT ARE CLEAR.
IT IS ALSO THE CASE THAT WE HAVE
NOT SEEN A PROPOSAL BESIDES THE
PRESIDENT'S THAT ACHIEVES THE
BALANCE THAT THE PRESIDENT
INSISTS BE PART OF THE DEAL.
>> THE PRESIDENT COULD ALSO WIN
A HUGE HIKE IN THE NATION'S DEBT
CEILING.
AUTHORITY TO RUN UP THE CREDIT
CARD ALMOST UNCHECKED FOR THE
NEXT TWO YEARS.
THAT'S WHAT HE WANTS.
JOHN BOEHNER'S HOUSE TODAY WILL
BE TO TRY TO SELL THIS
COMPROMISED POSITION TO THE
REPUBLICANS IN THE HOUSE.
>> WE ARE NEVER GOING TO GET A
PERFECT DEAL BUT I AM CONFIDENT
JOHN WILL BET THE BEST DEALING
CONSISTENT WITH REPUBLICANS.
>> NOT EVERYBODY BELIEVES THAT.
THEY WILL GIVE IN ON COST OF
LIVING INCREASES FOR SOCIAL
SEGMENT RECIPIENTS.
PAYROLL DEDUCTIONS WOULD
PROBABLY GO AWAY SO IT WOULD BE
A TAX HIKE ON THE MIDDLE CLASS.
>> DOUG LUZADER IN WASHINGTON,
THANK YOU.
>> NOW IT IS TIME TO GET THE
FIRST DEGREE WEATHER UPDATE WITH
MARIA MOLINA.
TALKING ABOUT A WARM-UP
POSSIBLY.
>> RIGHT.
GOOD MORNING EVERYONE.
IF YOU LIVE OUT WEST
TEMPERATURES ARE GOING TO BE LOW
AVERAGE FOR THIS TIME OF THE
YEAR.
YOU ARE SEE AGO BIT OF A COOL
DOWN AND A FRONTAL SYSTEM MOVING
IN SHOWERS WIDESPREAD FROM
WASHINGTON TO CALIFORNIA.
ACCUMULATIONS OVER A FOOT IN
SPOTS.
YOU COULD SEE ANYWHERE BETWEEN
6, 12 INCHES OF SNOW ACROSS
HIGHER ELEVATIONS.
THE RAINFALL IS DONE IN NEW YORK
CITY SO WE WILL BE DRYING THINGS
OUT.
IT WILL BE A LITTLE BREEZY OUT
THERE KEEP THAT IN MIND POSSIBLE
TRAVEL DELAYS BUT THE NEXT
WINTER STORM WE ARE EXPECTING
TODAY ACROSS PARTS OF THE
CENTRAL ROCKIES AND EVENTUALLY
IN THE PLAINS COULD BE THE FIRST
WINTER STORM OF THE SEASON
WEDNESDAY NIGHT AND ALSO
THURSDAY MORNING.
>> NOT LOOKING FORWARD TO THAT.
MARIA MOLINA, THANKS.
>> OO IT IS TIME NOW TO
ENTERTAIN THIS.
CHRISTOPHER CHENEY HAS BEEN
SENTENCED TO TEN YEARS BEHIND
BARS FOR HACKING INTO COMPUTERS
OF SCARLET JOHANSSON AND OTHERS
ON-LINE.
WHEN THE BALL DROPS IN NEW YORK
STAYS TIMES SQUARE THERE WILL BE
288 CRYSTAL PANELS ON IT.
THERE WILL BE DOVES CHISELLED IN
WITH A THEME LET THERE BE PEACE.
>> TRIBUTE DURING THE OPENING OF
THE VOICE.
♪
>> COACHES AND CONTESTANTS
HOLDING CARDS OF THE NAMES OF
EACH OF THE VICTIMS IN THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
>> THAT DEFINITELY BROUGHT TEARS
TO YOUR EYES LAST NIGHT.
>> TIME FOR THE TARTING LINEUP
FOUR TOP SPORTS STORIES.
NOW JUST A MEMORY.
THE TITANS BEAT THE JETS 14-10
TO ELIMINATE THEM FROM
CONTENTION.
AND NUMBER 10 IS NUMBER ONE.
ROBERT GRIFFIN THE THIRD SETTING
A SINGLE SEASON RECORD FOR
JERSEY SALES.
THE NFL SAID MORE PEOPLE BROUGHT
RG 3'S JERSEY THAN ANY OTHER
PLAYER FROM THE INTERNET SCORE.
YUKON PLAYING TRIBUTE TO THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
THE HUSKIES HELD A MOMENT OF
CENTER LINES BEFORE THE FIRST
GAME SINCE THE SHOOTING.
WOMEN AS BASKETBALL COACH ARIEMA
AND HIS WIFE DONATING 80,000
DOLLARS.
>> THE TIME NOW IS 43 MINUTES
AFTER THE HOUR.
SUPPOSED TO HELP REBUILD AFTER
SUPER STORM SANDY THE MONEY THEY
WERE SUPPOSED TO GET GOING TO
OTHER PLACES.
>> THEY ARE ADDING MILLIONS OF
DOLLARS BUT PEOPLE IN THE
NORTHEAST MIGHT NEVER
>> AN EMERGENCY SENATE BILL.
HURRICANE SANDY IS PACKED WITH
PORK.
HERE TO EXPLAIN IS DIANE MACEDO.
>> HI PATTI ANN.
THEY GANDHI BAITING THE
$64 BILLION BILL WHICH AIMS TO
REPAIR DAMAGE FROM SANDY AND
HELP PROTECT FROM FUTURE STORMS.
IN RESPONSE TO PRESIDENT OBAMA'S
REQUEST FOR 32 MILLION TO REPAIR
FROM THE AMTRAK RAIL SYSTEM IT
WILL BE MORE THAN 10 FORD TO
$346 MILLION TO COVER OPERATING
COSTS.
53 MILLION FOR FISHERY
DISASTERS.
HOPEFULLY IT WILL HELP WITH SHIN
HOOK SALMON.
MONEY IN THE BILL COULD BE USED
TO CLEAN UP DEBRIS ON THE COAST
THAT RIPPLED OVER FROM THE 2001
TSUNAMI IN JAPAN.
NEARLY 9 MILLION FOR THE
DEPARTMENT ADJUSTED AND HOMELAND
SECURITY.
THE SENATE BILL BYPASSED THE
COMMITTEE PROCESS AND IS GOING
STRAIGHT TO THE FLOOR WHERE
HARRY REID SAYS HE HOPE TO DO
SPEED THE BILL THROUGH THE
CHAMBER QUICKLY BUT IN THE HOUSE
THEY ARE CRAP BELLING WITH THE
SIZE OF THE BILL AND THE FACT
THAT THEY HAVEN'T FOUND A WAY TO
OFFSET THE COST.
WE WILL KEEP YOU POSTED.
>> DIANE MACEDO FOX BUSINESS
NETWORK.
>> WE WILL HAVE MORE COMING UP
ON FOX AND FRIENDS.
>>> THE TIME 48 AFTER THE HOUR.
NEXT ON "THE RUNDOWN"" ONE WOMAN
IN PITTSBURGH.
THIS IS A COOL STORY.
SHE GETS A GIFT FROM A COMPLETE
TRAININGER INSPIRED THE NEWTOWN
TRAGEDY.
>> ONLY A WEEK LEFT BEFORE
CHRISTMAS BUT THERE ARE PLENTY
OF WAYS TO SAVE ON YOUR
SHOPPING.
ANDREA WARICK IS UP NEXT WITH
TIPS.
>> NOW LET'S CHECK WITH BRIAN
KILMEADE ON FOX AND FRIENDS.
>> ANY ONE SHOPPING FOR ME DO
NOT CUT CORNERS.
>> MIA LOVE IS HERE LIVE IN THE
STUDIO TALKING ABOUT THE
ELEVATION OF TIM SCOTT AND SO
MUCH MORE ABOUT HER POLITICAL
CAREER AS WELL AS THE REPUBLICAN
PARTY.
ALSO THE ROLE OF MENTAL ILLNESS
WHEN STOPPING THE NEXT ATTACK
FROM HAPPENING AS WELL AS A BIG
PUSH FOR GUNS.
A MEETING FOR THE FIRST TIME IN
FIVE DAYS COULD A DEAL ALL BE
EMINENT?
IN FACT I GOT TO GO GET READY.
I'm Kirk Cameron. Four Hundred
years ago
our forefathers risked their
lives to bring this Bible to the
shores of America.
Because it contained
the principals for economic
liberty,
political liberty and religious
freedom. The 1599 Geneva Bible.
It was the first
complete english
translation, complete with
chapters,
numbered verses and 300,000
utterly unique study notes.
It actually came out
before the King James
Version and because the
government didn't authorize it,
it was outlawed. But it was a
Bible by the people,
for the people, the book
that built America.
And now for the first time
in 400 years it's
available again in a beautiful
leather edition. I have one,
I want you to have yours too.
Please visit GenevaBible.com
and get your copy
of this rare and historic
version of God's Word today.
Thank you and may God bless you.
>> WELCOME BACK.
A RECENT RASMUSSEN POLL SHOWS 49
PERCENT HAVE FINISHED THEIR
SHOPPING AND WHOPPING 32 PERCENT
HAVEN'T STARTED.
THAT DOESN'T MEAN YOU CAN'T
STILL GET A GOOD DEAL.
ANDREA WARREN IS HERE TO FILL US
IN.
FREE SHIPPING DAY WAS YESTERDAY
BUT IF YOU MISSED IT THERE'S
STILL HOPE.
>> THERE ARE RETARRYLS THAT ARE
EXTENDING THE GROUND SHIPPING
DEALS THROUGH THE REST OF THE
WEEK.
BANANA REPUBLIC HAS A DEADLINE
SET FOR TOMORROW.
NORDSTROMS SET FOR
DECEMBER 21ST.
YOU CAN STILL SHOP ON-LINE AND
GET THE GIFT IN TIME.
YOU HAVE TO MAKE SURE YOU REVIEW
THE DEADLINES TO MAKE SURE IT
DOESN'T GET LATE GO TO FREE
SHIPPING.COM A WINDOW WILL POP
UP THAT SHOWS SHIPPING IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS OR FREE
SHIPPING.ORG AND FIND THE
DISCOUNTED FREE SHIPPING RUSH
SHIPPING COUPON POSTS TO HELP
SAVE ON THAT.
>> PRESHIPPING.ORG FOR COUPONS.
>> SOME RETARRYL OFFERING FREE
OVERNIGHT TO STILL MAKE THE
EXTRA REVENUE FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
>> IN COMPARISON SHOPPING
COMPARISON SHOPPING.
>> AMAZON FLUCTUATED PRICING ON
A MICROWAVE FOUR TIMES IN 9
DAYS.
IT WILL ALERT YOU FOR THE SEARCH
IN PRICE DROP.
>> THEY WILL LET YOU KNOW WHEN
IT HAS DROPPED.
>> CLEAR COOKIES.
>> THEY STORE YOUR BROWSING
HISTORY AND YOUR OTHER DATA THAT
YOUR COMPUTER SENDS.
RETAILERS WILL OFTEN TIMES
PINPOINT DIFFERENT PRICE POINTS
BASED ON YOUR BROWSING HISTORY.
SOMETIMES THEY WILL OFFER DEALS
TO FIRST TIME VISITORS.
IF YOU CLEAR YOUR COOKIES YOU
MAY TRICK THEM AND GET A BETTER
DEAL.
>> ABONN DONE YOUR CART.
>> ABANDON YOUR CART YOU WILL
GET AN E-MAIL TO INCENTIVIZE YOU
TO GET BACK.
SOME ARE OFFERING COUPON POSTS
TO GET YOU TO GO BACK AND MAKE
THAT FINAL PURCHASE.
IT IS NOT SOMETHING WIDESPREAD
BUT GIVE IT A GO.
>> IF YOU TAKE A SCREEN SHOT OF
THE PAGE YOU CAN E-MAIL THAT TO
A CUSTOMER SERVICE REP WHO MAY
BE ABLE TO ADJUST THE PRICE ON
THE PRODUCT.
SOME RETARRYLS TARGET AND BEST
BUY WILL EVEN PRICE MATCH AFTER
THE PURCHASE.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
>> THE TIME 55 AFTER THE TOP OF
THE HOUR.
AN INSPIRATIONAL SONG ANOTHER
ONE OF THE GOOD DEEDS COMING OUT
OF THE TRAGEDY.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS KAREN AND JEREMIAH.
THEY DON'T KNOW IT YET,
BUT THEY'RE GONNA FALL IN LOVE,
GET MARRIED,
HAVE A COUPLE OF KIDS,
children laughing ]
MOVE TO THE COUNTRY,
D LIVE A LONG, HAPPY LIFE
TOGETHER
WHERE THEY ALMOST NEVER FIGHT
ABOUT MONEY.
[ dog barks ]
BECAUSE RIGHT AFTER
THEY GET MARRIED,
THEY'LL FIND
SOME RETIREMENT PEOPLE
WHO ARE PAID ON SALARY,
NOT COMMISSION.
THEY'LL GET
STRAIGHTFORWARD GUIDANCE
AND BE ABLE TO FOCUS ON OTHER
THINGS, LIKE EACH OTHER,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
♪
OUT OF THE TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN
COME STORIES OF KINDNESS.
CHILDREN ARE SMILING AGAIN
THARCHINGS TO THE GOLDEN
RETRIEVERS.
THE DOGS WERE SENT BY A
LUTHERAN CHURCH IN ILLINOIS TO
OFFER COMFORT DURING DIFFICULT
TIMES.
>> A PENNSYLVANIA WOMAN WAS
RECIPIENT OF A RANDOM ACT OF
CONFIDENCE.
SOMEONE LEFT A CARD WITH $10
IN MEMORY OF THE CHILDREN THAT
DIED