YOU KNOW, TO LOOK AT THAT
WOMAN, THAT SISTER WHO'S LOST
HER SISTER, WHO IS A TEACHER
AND TO KNOW THE PRINCIPAL HAS
PARENTS, PROBABLY, AND
SIBLINGS AND YOU KNOW, WE
CAN'T FORGET THE ADULTS AS
WELL WHO LOST THEIR LIVES, WHO
GAVE THEIR LIVES IN PROTECTION
OF THE CHILDREN.
>> AS WE LOOK BACK INSIDE,
GETTING READY FOR THIS, AND
OUTSIDE, LINING UP OUTSIDE AND
GETTING READY FOR THE SERVICE
INSIDE, STEVE, YOUR THOUGHTS
ABOUT, YOU KNOW, DEALING WITH
THIS AND IS ALSO THAT, I KNOW
YOU SEE SENATOR JOE LIEBERMAN
IN LINE AND OBVIOUSLY, HE WAS
OUT HERE ON FOX NEWS SUNDAY
TALKING ABOUT DEALING WITH
THIS AND ALSO, AS YOU
MENTIONED, SOMETHING WE TALKED
ABOUT, HOLLYWOOD, VIDEO GAMES
AND OTHER ASPECTS TO WHAT NINA
TALKS ABOUT, THE BROAD,
PERHAPS, COMMISSION APPROACH
TO A BIGGER PROBLEM.
>> YEAH, I THINK IF YOU -- IF
YOU -- YOU KNOW, BASICALLY
THERE'S GOING TO BE THIS BROAD
NATIONAL DISCUSSION, I HOPE
IT'S BROADER RATHER THAN MORE
NARROW, BUT WHAT STRUCK ME
FROM THE WORDS FROM ROBBIE
PARKER YESTERDAY AS HE
REMEMBERED HIS DAUGHTER WHO
DIED IN THE SHOOTING WAS THAT
HE TOOK THE TIME TO REMEMBER
AND THINK ABOUT THE FAMILY OF
THE SHOOTER, WHICH I JUST
FOUND, YOU KNOW, AS A
OF A SEVEN-YEAR-OLD,
FIVE-YEAR-OLD AND A
TWO-YEAR-OLD, TO SEE HIM TAKE
THAT TIME IN THAT MOMENT AS
HE'S TAKING AND REMEMBERING
HIS OWN DAUGHTER AND REMEMBER
THE FAMILY OF THE SHOOTER AND
SAY, I'M NOT MAD, I FORGIVE
THEM, I'M THINKING ABOUT THEM
AT THIS TIME WAS JUST AN
INCREDIBLY POWERFUL MOMENT,
AND MAKES HIM, I THINK, A VERY
STRONG MAN.
>> AND I THINK THAT'S A
REMARKABLE EXAMPLE OF GRACE IN
THE WORLD THAT A FATHER WOULD
THINK OF THAT.
IF I COULD SAY ONE WORD ABOUT
THE POLICY, I THINK THE
NATIONAL COMMISSION IS THE WAY
TO GO TO TAKE IT OUT OF THE
MOMENT.
AND I THINK OF THE -- WHEN I
MENTIONED THE OTHER DAY THERE
HAD BEEN THREE ELEMENTS ARE
THE SHOOTER, THE WEAPON, AND
THE ENVIRONMENT.
AND ALL THREE SHOULD BE GIVEN
EQUAL PLACE IN ANY INQUIRY,
MEANING THE AVAILABILITY OF
GUNS, THE QUESTION OF THE
VIDEO GAME AND THE MOVIE,
HOLLYWOOD INDUSTRY, WHICH
DESENSITIZES AND MAKES ALMOST
A GAME OF THE VIOLENCE, I
WOULDN'T BE SURPRISED IF WE
LEARNED THAT THE SHOOTER WAS
PLAYING GAMES, YOU KNOW, ON
HIS OWN IN HIS AUTISTIC WORLD
AND MANY OF WHICH ARE ABOUT
MASSACRE, MOWING DOWN PEOPLE
AND THE THIRD IS, OF COURSE,
THE PSYCHOLOGY OF THE SHOOTER.
AND INTERESTINGLY, EACH OF
THEM IMPINGES ON A RIGHT, A
FUNDAMENTAL RIGHT, GUN CONTROL
ON THE SECOND, THE
ENTERTAINMENT INDUSTRY, FREE
SPEECH, THE FIRST.
AND THE IDEA OF COMMITTING A
PERSON, THE FIFTH.
HE SO, THESE ARE REALLY
ROUNDING ISSUES, VERY DEEP IN
OUR LIBERAL, SORT OF
LIBERTARIAN CULTURE, BUT I
THINK IF YOU DEAL WITH
ANYTHING YOU HAVE TO DEAL WITH
ALL THREE AT ONCE.
>> AND I SHOULD POINT OUT
YOU'RE LOOKING LIVE AT THE
AUDITORIUM AT THE NEWTOWN HIGH
SCHOOL.
ABOUT 900 PEOPLE FIT AND AN
OVERFLOW IN THE GYM OF 1300
AND STAFF AND STUDENTS OF
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY ARE
ACTUALLY IN THE CROWD AND
THEY'RE WEARING GREEN AND
WHITE RIBBONS.
THE TOWN'S AND THE SCHOOL'S
COLORS WITH A SMALL ANGEL IN
THE MIDDLE OF THEM.
WE'RE TOLD THAT THIS SERVICE
WILL BE DELAYED A BIT BECAUSE
THE PRESIDENT IS STILL MEETING
WITH THESE FAMILY MEMBERS AND
CLASSROOMS AT THE HIGH SCHOOL.
AND HE'S TAKING HIS TIME WITH
THESE FAMILIES IN INDIVIDUAL
CLASSROOMS.
WE DON'T HAVE A START TIME
YET.
IT COULD BE POSSIBLY AT THE
BOTTOM OF THE HOUR.
WE DON'T KNOW AS OF YET.
THEY'LL GIVE US THE BEST CUES
THEY CAN, BUT HE IS MEETING
WITH THESE--
WITH THESE FAMILIES ONE BY ONE
AND ALSO MEETING WITH FIRST
RESPONDERS.
AND PICKING UP ON WHAT CHARLES
SAID.
>> YEAH, I MEAN, I WAS JUST
GOING TO POINT OUT WHEN YOU
TALK ABOUT, YOU KNOW, HEROES
AND HUMAN MOMENTS AND THE
STORIES THAT WE'VE HEARD ABOUT
THESE TEACHERS OVER THE COURSE
OF THE LAST 24 HOURS.
>> THE PRINCIPAL AND--
>> THE PRINCIPAL.
>> THE PSYCHIATRIST.
>> AND LOSING THEIR LIVES AND
TRYING TO PROTECT THE KIDS AND
THEN THERE WERE TEACHERS WHO
HID IN CLOSETS WITH CHILDREN
AND GOT THEM TO DRAW TO CALM
THEM DOWN AND ONE TEACHER TOLD
THEM SHE LOVED THEM, FEARFUL
THAT THEY WOULD HEAR THAT
INSTEAD OF THE GUNFIRE.
I MEAN, THESE WERE REALLY
HEROES IN THE BEST, BEST SENSE
OF THE WORD.
>> YEAH, I MEAN, THOSE ARE THE
STORIES, GETTING INTO THE
ROOMS, LOOKING THEM UP.
SOME TEACHERS PUTTING THEM
THROUGH WINDOWS SO THEY COULD
GET OUT IN TIME, KIRSTEN,
THINKING TO GET THEM, YOU
KNOW, REALLY WHAT THEY'D BEEN
TRAINED TO DO IN THE SENSE OF
EMERGENCY AND REMEMBER THAT
THIS PLACE IS JUST, AN IDYLLIC
KIND OF PLACE.
>> TOWN, YEAH, I MEAN, MY
BROTHER IS A TEACHER AND I
HAVE SO MUCH RESPECT FOR
TEACHER AND THEY LOVE TEAR
KIDS SO MUCH AND I DON'T
THINK, YOU KNOW, THIS IS THE
ULTIMATE SACRIFICE THAT WE SAW
WHAT THE TEACHERS ARE DOING.
I THINK SOMETIMES PEOPLE DON'T
ALWAYS APPRECIATE JUST HOW
MUCH THEY REALLY DO LOVE THESE
KIDS AND REALLY GIVE THEIR
LIVES TO THEM EVERY SINGLE DAY
AND THEN IN THIS WAY, IN THE
ULTIMATE WAY.
AND BY THROWING THEMSELVES IN
FRONT OF THIS GUNMAN, THEY
DELAYED, YOU KNOW, ENOUGH FOR
THE FIRST RESPONDERS TO GET
THERE BECAUSE THE FIRST
RESPONDERS SAID THERE WAS SO
MUCH AMMO LEFT OVER, THAT HE
BASICALLY, THE SHOOTER KILLED
HIMSELF BECAUSE THE FIRST
RESPONDERS SHOWED UP AND I
GUESS HE DIDN'T WANT THEM TO
BE ABLE TO KILL HIM OR CAPTURE
HIM.
SO, WE DON'T EVEN KNOW HOW
MUCH WORSE THE CARNAGE WOULD
HAVE BEEN, HAD THE PRINCIPAL,
HAD THE TEACHER NOT, YOU KNOW,
DELAYED HIM.
>> LIKE WE'VE SAID, STEVE, WE
DON'T KNOW SO MUCH ABOUT THIS
COMPLETE STORY AND SO MUCH
MORE COULD POTENTIALLY COME
OUT ABOUT THIS.
>> YEAH, I SUSPECT WE'LL LEARN
A LOT MORE ABOUT WHAT THE
TEACHERS DID AND WHAT THE
ADMINISTRATORS DID AND IT'S
THE CASE THAT TEACHERS TAKE
THIS PERSONALLY, FOR THE VAST
MAJORITY OF TEACHERS, GOING TO
SCHOOL EVERY DAY IS NOT JUST
SHOWING UP AT A JOB.
THEY TAKE THIS PERSONALLY.
THEY'RE PERSONALLY INVESTED IN
THE LIVES OF THEIR STUDENTS
AND WHEN THEIR STUDENTS DON'T
DO WELL, THE TEACHERS GO HOME
AND THEY WORRY ABOUT IT AT
NIGHT AND I THINK WHAT YOU'VE
SEEN AND KIRSTEN SUGGESTS SORT
OF THE ULTIMATE MANIFESTATION
OF THAT LEVEL OF CARING AND IN
THIS KIND OF AN EVENT, THAT
THE TEACHERS DO, YOU KNOW,
THESE KIND OF -- THEY TAKE
THIS KIND OF CARE ON A DAILY
BA
SIS AND YOU JUST DON'T SEE IT
IN THIS WAY.
>> WE'RE AGAIN AWAITING THIS
PRAYER VIGIL AND THIS SERVICE
AND REMARKS OF PRESIDENT OBAMA
WHO IS MEETING WITH FAMILY
MEMBERS AND EXPECTED TO TAKE
THE STAGE AT THE NEWTOWN HIGH
SCHOOL, IN A BIT HE'LL LOOK TO
OBVIOUSLY, COMFORT THIS TOWN,
STILL TRYING TO COMPREHEND AND
DEAL WITH THIS TRAGEDY.
CHIEF WHITE HOUSE
CORRESPONDENT ED HENRY IS LIVE
OUTSIDE THE SCHOOL.
AND ED, THE LATEST THERE?
>> Reporter: WELL, BRET, WHAT
WE'RE HEARING IS TAKING THE
PRESIDENT SOME TIME IS EACH
INDIVIDUAL FAMILIES IN THE
CLASSROOM, WHAT YOU'RE SEEING
IS THE AUDITORIUM WHERE THE
PRESIDENT AND OTHER
DIGNITARIES WILL SPEAK AT THE
PRAYER VIGIL.
INSIDE THERE ARE CLASSROOMS
SET UP FOR EACH FAMILY TO GET
PRIVATE TIME WITH THE
PRESIDENT AND OBVIOUSLY A GRIM
TASK WITH ANY
COMMANDER-IN-CHIEF AND THEY
HAVE TO DEAL WITH THIS WHEN
FAMILIES LOST LOVED ONES IN
AFGHANISTAN AND NOW IT'S RIGHT
HERE AT HOME AND AS YOU NOTED
EARLIER MANY TIMES THE LAST
COUPLE OF HOURS, IT'S HAPPENED
TOO MANY TIMES OVER THE
PRESIDENT'S FIRST TERM IN
OFFICE.
I WILL NOTE THOUGH THAT PEOPLE
IN THIS COMMUNITY ARE GETTING
A LOT OF STRENGTH FROM ALL
CORNERS OF THE COUNTRY, ALL
CORNERS OF THE GLOBE.
I SPOKE TO A RED CROSS
VOLUNTEER WHO CAME FROM
GREENSBORO, NORTH CAROLINA,
SAYS THERE ARE AT LEAST A
HUNDRED VOLUNTEERS FROM THE
RED CROSS WHO COME FROM ACROSS
AMERICA, HANDING OUT BLANKETS
TO THE PEOPLE WAITING OUT HERE
IN THE FREEZING COLD TO GET
INTO THE VIGIL AND HANDING OUT
STUFFED ANIMALS AND APPEAR TO
BE SOME SORT OF DOGS OR
SOMETHING FOR THE KIDS SO THEY
HAVE SOMETHING TO BRING A
SMILE TO THEIR FACES AND
THEY'RE WAITING FOR THIS
DIFFICULT EVENING TO CONTINUE
FORWARD.
ALSO, A GENTLEMAN WHO HAS BEEN
KIND ENOUGH TO LET US USE HIS
PROPERTY FOR LIVE SHOTS HERE,
ROB AND SUSAN, THEY GO TO
UNITED METHODIST CHURCH HERE
AND TOLD US THAT THEIR BISHOP
SAID TODAY THEY HAD GOTTEN
MESSAGES, THIS UNITED
METHODIST CHURCH FROM ZIMBABWE
AND THEY'RE GETTING PRAYERS
FROM ALL AROUND THE WORLD AND
THEY'RE DRAWING STRENGTH.
AND THE PEOPLE WAITING TO GET
IN HERE.
THERE'S NO PARKING AND CARS
LINED UP ON EITHER SIDE OF ME
AND A HIGHWAY TO MY RIGHT JUST
PAST THE HIGH SCHOOL AND ONE
WOMAN WHO JUST WALKED BY AND I
ASKED A WOMAN WHERE SHE'D
PARKED HER CAR AND SHE SAID
EXIT 10 OFF THE HIGHWAY ON THE
OTHER SIDE OF THE HIGH SCHOOL
AND I SAID HOW FAR IS THAT?
TWO MILES, SHE WAS WALKING
WITH OTHER PEOPLE, SHE WAS
WALKING TWO MILES IN THE RAIN
JUST TO BE AT THIS PRAYER
VIGIL.
IT GIVES YOU AN IDEA OF THE
DEPTH OF THE PAIN PEOPLE ARE
FEELING, BUT THE SUPPORT
THEY'RE WILLING TO GIVE ONE
ANOTHER TONIGHT, BRET.
>> YEAH, PRETTY AMAZING.
AND DO WE KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT
THE SPEECH AS OF YET, THE
PRESIDENT'S SPEECH?
>> ALL WE -- ALL WE KNOW ABOUT
THE PRESIDENT'S SPEECH IS THAT
SOME OF HIS ADVERTISERS HAVE
SAID HE DOES NOT WANT TO TALK
ABOUT GUN CONTROL AND SOME OF
THE ISSUES THAT HAVE COME OUT
IN TERMS OF PUBLIC POLICIES
BECAUSE HE THINKS THAT GIVEN
EVERYTHING LAID OUT ABOUT THE
COMMUNITY IT'S NOT THE TIME OR
PLACE TO DO IT, BUT AS YOU
KNOW, THERE ARE SOME, LIKE NEW
YORK CITY MAYOR MICHAEL
BLOOMBERG, SAYING EVERY TIME
THERE'S A TRAGEDY LIKE THIS,
TUCSON, AURORA AND NOW IS NOT
THE TIME TO TALK ABOUT IT.
HE BELIEVES IT'S THE TIME TO
TALK ABOUT IT.
AND YOU MENTIONED SENATOR JOE
LIEBERMAN HE TALKED TO
REPORTERS AND TALKED ABOUT THE
COMMISSION YOU MENTIONED HE'S
NOW PUSHING, NOT JUST WITH GUN
CONTROL, BUT TAKE A LOOK AT
VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES AND
VIOLENCE FROM HOLLYWOOD, WHAT
KIND OF ROLE THAT MAY PLAY, IN
TERMS OF AFFECTING CHILDREN
AND WHAT NOT.
SO, SENATOR LIEBERMAN WHO IS
RETIRING MAY OBVIOUSLY BE
SOMEBODY WHO COULD LEAD A
COMMISSION LIKE THAT, WE'LL
SEE IF THE PRESIDENT REACHES
OUT TO HIM ON THAT.
WE'RE TOLD THAT THE PRESIDENT
WILL NOT TALK ABOUT THE PUBLIC
POLICY ISSUES, HE WANTS THIS
TO BE ABOUT PRAYER AND
REMEMBRANCE, BRET.
>> AS WE'RE LOOKING LIVE
THERE, WE SEE THE TABLE IN
FRONT OF THE PODIUM THERE AND
I THINK THAT THAT IS--
THOSE ARE CANDLES, PROBABLY 26
CANDLES THERE ON THE STAGE TO
REPRESENT THE 26 PEOPLE KILLED
INSIDE THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
AS IT PULLS BACK AND SOME OF
THE MEMBERS OF THE LOCAL
CLERGY AND RELIGIOUS FOLKS WHO
MAY BE SPEAKING AT THIS
CEREMONY, YOU'VE COVERED THIS
PRESIDENT FOR A NUMBER OF
YEARS NOW.
AND AS WE'VE SAID, HE'S DONE A
NUMBER OF THESE SPEAKING
EVENTS, BUT WHAT ABOUT MEETING
WITH VICTIMS'S FAMILIES AND
MEETING WITH FAMILIES THAT
HAVE LOST LOVED ONES.
YOUR PERSONAL KNOWLEDGE NHOW HE
DEALS WITH THOSE SITUATIONS
AND WHAT YOU KNOW ABOUT THAT.
>> SURE, IN TALKING TO SOME OF
HIS ADVISORS SAY THIS IS
SOMETHING HE DOES OFTEN, WHEN
HE I MENTION BRAVE MEN AND
WOMEN WHO DIED IN AFGHANISTAN
AND DIED PREVIOUSLY IN IRAQ
AND HE MEETS WITH THE FAMILIES
AND DOES IT PRIVATELY.
I REMEMBER, YOU REMEMBER
COVERING PRESIDENT BUSH AS
WELL AND WE DON'T HEAR ABOUT
IT, THEY DO IT BEHIND CLOSED
DOORS AND HE DON'T HAVE
TELEVISION CAMERAS AND YOU
KNOW HOW PAINFUL THE VETERANS
THAT PAY THE ULTIMATE PRICE GO
THROUGH, THEIR FAMILIES.
NOW IT'S HAPPENING AT HOME.
IN TALKING TO SOME OF HIS
ADVISORS, HE SAYS WHAT WE SAW
ON FRIDAY, WITH THE PRESIDENT
I WAS SITTING IN THE BRIEFING
ROOM AND AFTER FOUR YEARS OF
COVERING HIM YOU'VE NEVER SEEN
HIM, DESPITE THE PREVIOUS
TRAGEDY, BREAK DOWN THE WAY HE
DID ON FRIDAY AND STRUGGLE AT
ONE POINT, YOU COULD HEAR A
PIN DROP IN THE WHITE HOUSE
BRIEFING ROOM AND AS THE
PRESIDENT WAS STRUGGLING TO
KEEP HIS COMPOSURE FOR 7, 8,
10 SECONDS, GIVES YOU AN IDEA
HOW DIFFICULT IT IS FOR HIM,
AS HE MENTIONED, NOT JUST AS A
PRESIDENT, BUT AS A PARENT.
AND I WILL NOTE THAT ON FRIDAY
WHEN HE MENTIONED THAT THIS
WEEKEND, HE AND THE FIRST LADY
WOULD HUG THEIR OWN CHILDREN A
LITTLE BIT TIGHTER, BEFORE THE
PRESIDENT CAME OVER HERE TO
TALK ABOUT THESE CHILDREN WHO
SO TRAGICALLY LOST THEIR
LIVES, HE SPENT SOME TIME IN
WASHINGTON.
HIS DAUGHTER SASHA HAD A
RECITAL, A DANCE RECITAL
REHEARSAL BACK IN WASHINGTON
AND HE REALIZES HE'S GOT HIS
TWO DAUGHTERS HE WAS THINKING
ABOUT, PARENTS OR FOLKS WHO,
YOU KNOW, HAVE NIECES AND
NEPHEWS ARE ALL THINKING ABOUT
THEM THIS WEEKEND.
THE PRESIDENT INCLUDED, BRET.
>> OKAY.
ED.
THOSE CANDLES IN FACT WERE TO
REPRESENT THE 20 CHILDREN AND
SIX ADULTS KILLED IN SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL THERE
ON THE STAGE, GETTING READY
FOR THIS VIGIL AND PRAYER
SERVICE.
ED HENRY, THANK YOU VERY MUCH
AND AGAIN, FOR MORE ON HOW YOU
CAN HELP THE COMMUNITY OF
NEWTOWN, GO TO FOXNEWS.COM AND
THERE ON THE FRONT PAGE YOU
CAN SEE THE HIGHLIGHTED AREA
IN RED, THE SANDY HOOK SUPPORT
FUND, AMONG THAT IN THERE, YOU
CAN SEE THE AMERICAN RED CROSS
AND OTHER GROUPS, BUT ON THE
FRONT PAGE FOXNEWS.COM, A WAY
THAT YOU CAN HELP.
WE'RE WAITING THIS PRAYER
SERVICE TO BEGIN AND THE
PRESIDENT IS MEETING WITH THE
VICTIM'S FAMILIES.
AND YOU CAN SEE ALL OF IT HERE
ON FOX NEWS CHANNEL, SPECIAL
COVERAGE FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
♪
THE FINANCIAL OBSTACLES
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAN
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
>>  LOOKING LIVE THERE IN THE
AUDITORIUM OF NEWTOWN HIGH
SCHOOL, PEOPLE GETTING READY
THERE.
IN FACT, 900 IN THAT
AUDITORIUM, 1300 IN THE
OVERFLOW GYM.
NOW, YOU CAN SEE SOME FOLKS
THERE GIVING EACH OTHER A HUG
WITH A LITTLE BABY.
AND THEY'RE GETTING READY, BUT
IT COULD BE SOME TIME BEFORE
THE PRESIDENT FINISHES MEETING
WITH SOME OF THE FAMILIES IN
THE CLASSROOMS.
ONE BY ONE, WE'RE TOLD,
MEETING WITH THE FAMILIES IN
DIFFERENT CLASSROOMS, IN THAT
HIGH SCHOOL, HAVING INDIVIDUAL
TIME WITH THE VICTIMS FAMILY
MEMBERS, AS WELL AS THE FIRST
RESPONDERS.
THIS CEREMONY, PRAYER VIGIL,
INTERFAITH CEREMONY WILL START
WHEN HE ENTERS THE ROOM AND
THEN WE'LL BRING THAT ALL TO
YOU LIVE HERE ON FOX NEWS
CHANNEL AS WELL AS FOX
BROADCAST.
WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE
VICTIMS OF THIS TRAGEDY,
PUTTING FACES AND
PERSONALITIES TO EACH OF THE
26 NAMES, 27 INCLUDING THE
MOTHER OF THE SHOOTER, SIX
CHILDREN--
SIX ADULTS, 20 CHILDREN.
WE'RE MEETING THE FAMILIES OF
THESE VICTIMS.
HORRIBLE TRAGEDY RIPPING,
RIPPLING OUT, IMPACTING THE
ENTIRE NEWTOWN AND OF COURSE
THE ENTIRE NATION.
MOLLY LINE IS LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
WHAT ELSE DO WE KNOW ABOUT THE
VICTIMS TONIGHT?
>> RIGHT, THERE WAS THAT
HORRIBLE ANTICIPATION THE
FIRST HOURS AFTER THE SHOOTING
AS THIS ENTIRE COMMUNITY WAS
WAITING TO FIND OUT WHO THEY
WOULD BE AND WHAT THEIR NAMES
WOULD BE.
WE KNEW THERE WOULD BE 20
CHILDREN AND WE'RE JUST
BEGINNING TO GET A LOOK AT
SOME OF THEIR FACES AND FIND
OUT ABOUT WHAT THEY LIKED TO
DO AND ENJOYED IN THE SHORT
LIVES THEY HAD LIVED.
JESSI
JESSICA JUST SIX-YEAR-OLD,
BRUNETTE, A BEAUTIFUL SMILE.
HER MOTHER A TEACHER IN A
NEARBY SCHOOL.
>> AND DANIEL, HIS FATHER IS
MUSICIAN, HIS MOTHER LOVED HIM
VERY, VERY MUCH, AS A FIRST
GRADER, HE LOVED TO PLAY
SOCCER.
THESE SMALL LITTLE DETAILS
ABOUT KIDS JUST BEGINNING
THEIR LIVES AND THINGS THEY
LIKED TO DO, ARE REALLY THE
THINGS THAT KIDS ALL ACROSS
AMERICA LIKE TO DO.
BRET.
>> Bret: MOLLY, WE'VE SEEN THE
OUTPOURING OF SUPPORT FROM ALL
OVER THE COUNTRY, BUT HOW IS
THE COMMUNITY REACTING
INTERNALLY?
>> THIS IS A COMMUNITY THAT
ALL HAS BEEN STRUCK IN SO MANY
DIFFERENT WAYS, THE INITIAL
FEAR, THE PULLING TOGETHER, IN
THE MOMENTS THAT THIS WAS
HAPPENING, EVERYONE YOU SPEAKHA
TOWN AND THE STORY THE MOMENT
THEY HEARD THIS WAS HAPPENING
AND THE MOMENTS LEADING UP TO
IT, THE WAITING FOR THE NAMES
AND EVERYTHING AFTERWARDS.
WE HAVE SEEN PACKED CHURCH
SERVICES ALL ACROSS THIS
COMMUNITY, OUTPOURING SO FULL
AND SO BIG THAT PEOPLE HAVE
BEEN FILLED TO THE BRIM,
POURING OUT OF THESE CHURCHES
OUTSIDE, AND WHEN YOU ASK
ANYONE, WHY ARE YOU HERE?
AND EVEN BEFORE THEY KNEW THE
NAMES OF THE VICTIMS.
THEY FELT A PULL TO BE HERE IN
THE COMMUNITY.
THEY UNDERSTAND IT'S A LONG
PROCESS AS FAR AS REBUILDING,
THAT THE IMPACT STRUCK IN SO
MANY DIFFERENT WAYS.
NOT JUST THE PEOPLE THAT LOST
THEIR CHILDREN OR LOST A LOVED
ONE, A MOTHER, A SISTER, BUT
THOSE WHOSE CHILDREN SURVIVED
THIS MASSACRE, THERE'S NO JOY
IN THAT, INSTEAD THEY SAY A
LITTLE BIT OF RELIEF, RELIEF
TO HAVE FOUND THEIR CHILD
ALIVE, BUT AT THE SAME TIME A
BITTERSWEET ONE, UNDERSTANDING
SO MANY OTHERS ARE SUFFERING
SO GREATLY AND A LOT OF
UNANSWERED QUESTIONS AS TO
WHAT'S NEXT AND HOW TO REBUILD
AND HOW TO MOVE FORWARD, NOT
JUST THE LAYING TO REST OF
THOSE THAT HAVE PASSED, BUT
HELPING THOSE THAT SURVIVE
THIS TO MOVE ON.
BRET.
>> Bret: MOLLY, QUICKLY, YOU
TALK ABOUT CHURCH SERVICES
TODAY.
ANYONE TALK ABOUT THIS SERVICE
TONIGHT AND WHAT THIS IT MEANS
FOR THEM?
>> YOU KNOW, THE PEOPLE IN
THIS COMMUNITY KNOW THIS IS A
SMALL TOWN AND EVERYONE KNOWS
EACH OTHER AND THEY'VE SEEN
THAT PULLING TOGETHER, BUT
HAVING THE PRESIDENT ARRIVE
HERE TONIGHT, GIVES THIS
COMMUNITY AN ACCEPTS  SENSE OF
THIS IS.
IT'S NOT JUST NEWTOWN, IT'S
ALL OF THE COUNTRY THINKING
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED HERE,
BRET.
>> Bret: MOLLY LINE, LIVE IN
NEWTOWN.
AGAIN, AS YOU LOOK LIVE IN THE
AUDITORIUM, NEWTOWN HIGH
SCHOOL, WE'RE WAITING
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S REMARKS FOR
THE PRAYER SERVICE AND AS SOON
AS HE WALKS IN.
AND WE'LL HAVE THAT.
AND 26 PEOPLE KILLED AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
20 OF THEM CHILDREN, SIX AND
SEVEN YEARS OLD.
OUR SPECIAL COVERAGE OF THE
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT
CONTINUES AFTER THIS.
♪
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
GOVERNOR OF GETTING IT DONE.
YOU KNOW HOW TO DANCE...
WITH A DEADLINE.
AND YOU...RENT FROM NATIONAL.
BECAUSE ONLY NATIONAL LETS YOU
CHOOSE ANY CAR IN THE AISLE...
AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE A FULL-SIZE
OR ABOVE,
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
THIS IS AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS, BUSINESS PRO.
YES, IT IS.
GO NATIONAL. GO LIKE A PRO.
♪
>>  WELCOME BACK, AS WE AWAIT
THIS PRAYER VIGIL FOR THE
VICTIMS OF THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
WE'RE GETTING NEW INFORMATION
ABOUT THE INVESTIGATION.
ATF INVESTIGATORS ARE NOW
CONFIRMING WHAT WE BROUGHT TO
YOU FROM THE ASSOCIATED PRESS
EARLIER, THAT NANCY LANZA, THE
GUNMAN'S MOTHER DID VISIT ONE,
PROBABLY MORE LOCAL GUN RANGES
AND THERE'S MORE TO WHAT WE
BROUGHT YOU EARLIER.
MIKE TOBIN IS IN NEWTOWN WITH
THAT.
WHAT'S THE NEW INFORMATION
COMING IN ON THAT, MIKE?
>> SO THE NEW INFORMATION IS
ALSO THAT ADAM LANZA, THE
GUNMAN HAD VISITED A GUN RANGE
SOMEWHERE IN THE HE LOCAL AREA
AND NO CONFIRMATION THAT ADAM
LANZA ACTUALLY FIRED A GUN.
NO CONFIRMATION THAT NANCY
TOOK HIM TO THE THE GUN RANGE,
JUST NA ADAM LANZA HAD BEEN TO
A GUN RANGE IN THE LOCAL AREA
AND NANCY LANZA HAD BEEN TO A
GUN RANGE.
AND STORIES THAT NANCY LANZA
WOULD TAKE ADAM OUT TO THE GUN
RANGE, THIS IS PART OF THE
INVESTIGATION FROM THE BUREAU
OF ALCOHOL, TOBACCO FIREARMS
AND MORE THAN 80 LICENSED
FIREARM FACILITIES IN A TEN
MILE RADIUS, BRET.
>> Bret: MIKE, SHE WAS, FROM
ON THE GROUND REPORTS, A GUN
ENTHUSIAST, THAT THOSE GUNS
WERE LEGAL AND REGISTERED AND
WE ASSUME FROM AUTHORITIES
WHAT THEY'VE SAID, THAT ADAM
TOOK THOSE GUNS AND HE
ACTUALLY HAD FOUR WEAPONS WITH
HIM?
>> HE HAD FOUR WEAPONS AND
QUITE AN ARSENAL WITH HIM.
THE STATE POLICE OUT HERE SAY
THAT HUNDREDS OF ROUNDS OF
AMMUNITION WAS FIRED AND MANY
MORE READY TO GO.
THE PRIMARY WEAPON USED IN
THIS WAS A BUSH MASTER, AR-15
ASSAULT RIFLE AND THAT WAS
COUPLED WITH 30 ROUND CLIPS HE
WAS USING AT THE TIME
ACCORDING TO STATE POLICE AND
NOT ONLY THAT CARRYING WITH
HIM A COUPLE OF SIDE ARMS, AND
.9 MILLIMETER AND THE OTHER A
GLOCK .10 MILLIMETER AND ONE
OF THOSE SIDE ARMS WAS USE
TODAY KILL THE GUNMAN HIMSELF
WHEN THE FIRST RESPONDERS
ARRIVED ON THE SCENE AND A
FOURTH WEAPON, WE'RE NOT SURE
IF IT WAS USED IN THE ATTACKS
BECAUSE ACCORDING TO THE STATE
POLICE, HE WAS OUT IN THE CAR
CARRIED OUT IN THE SCHOOL, A
SHOTGUN IN THE CAR.
ALL OF THESE WEAPONS ARE
IMPORTANT TO THE INVESTIGATION
AND STATE POLICE SAY THEY WILL
TRACE THESE BACK TO THE WORK
BENCH ON WHICH THEY WERE MADE
AND TRACE EVERY TIME THESE
GUNS WERE SOLD AND EVERY TIME
THEY WERE FIRED TO TRY TO GET
A TIME LINE, AS FAR AS WHAT
LED UP TO THIS HORRIFIC
SHOOTING, BRET.
>> Bret: ONE WOULD THINK YOU
WOULD HAVE TO HAVE TRAINING TO
SHOOT THAT MANY ROUNDS, ONE
WOULD THINK?
>> YOU WOULD, AND IT SEEMS
THAT ADAM LANZA, FROM WHAT YOU
HEAR AS FAR AS HIS ATTENTION
TO DETAIL, AND WORKING WITH
COMPUTERS AND DIFFERENT THINGS
HE DID WITH LAN, LOCAL AREA
NETWORK, THAT HE HAD A GOOD
MIND FOR DETAIL, A GOOD MIND
FOR PARTICULARS.
NOW, AS FAR AS WHAT HE KNEW
ABOUT WEAPONS, YOU WOULD
REALLY JUST HAVE TO SPECULATE.
AGAIN SHALL THE BEST
INFORMATION WE HAVE RIGHT NOW,
AT SOME POINT HE WAS AT A GUN
RANGE, THAT COMING FROM A
SPOKESMAN FOR--
A SPOKESWOMAN FROM THE ATF AND
THAT'S REALLY AS FAR AS WE
KNOW.
BUT WE KNOW THAT HE HAD GOOD
KNOWLEDGE EVER WORKING THINGS
AND COMPUTERS AND WHAT NOT,
BRET.
>> Bret: ALL RIGHT, TOBIN,
FOLLOWING THE INVESTIGATION,
MIKE, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
AND AS YOU LOOK LIVE THERE IN
THE AUDITORIUM, THE CONSOLING
AND HUGGING GOING ON AS
PRESIDENT OBAMA BECOMES
CONSOLER IN CHIEF TONIGHT.
AND IN A FEW MINUTES WE'RE
TOLD THIS PRAYER SERVICE WILL
GET UNDERWAY, THIS TOWN,
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THE FACULTY MEMBERS AND SOME
STUDENTS ARE ACTUALLY WEARING
GREEN AND WHITE RIBBONS, THE
SCHOOL, THAT'S THEIR SCHOOL
COLORS IN SANDY HOOK,
ELEMENTARY, THERE YOU SEE
THEM, TOWN COLORS, IN THE
MIDDLE, AN ANGEL, 20 OF THEM
KILLED FRIDAY.
♪
[ sniffs ] I HAVE A COLD.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
AVOID BAD.FATS.
DON'T GO OVER 2000...
1200 CALORIES A DAY.
CARBS ARE BAD. CARBS ARE GOOD.
THE STORY KEEPS CHANGING.
SO I'M NOT LISTENING...
TO ANYONE BUT MYSELF.
I KNOW BETTER NUTRITION
WHEN I SEE IT:
GREAT GRAINS.
GREAT GRAINS CEREAL STARTS
WHOLE AND STAYS WHOLE.
SEE THE SEAM?
MORE PROCESSED FLAKES LOOK
NOTHING LIKE NATURALRAINS.
YOU CAN'T ARGUE WITH
NUTRITION YOU CAN SEE.
GREAT GRAINS.
SEARCH GREAT GRAINS
AND SEE FOR YOURSELF.
FOR MULTI GRAIN FLAKES TT ARE
ANXCELLENT SOURCE OF FIBER
TRY GREAT GRAINS
BANANA NUT CRUNCH
AND CRANBERRY ALMOND CRUNCH.
Neural speeds
increasing to 4G LTE.
Brain upgrading to a quad-core
processor.
Predictive intelligence
with Google Now complete.
Introducing DROID DNA by HTC.
It's not an upgrade
to your phone.
It's an upgrade to yourself.
(APPLAUS
(APPLAUSE)
>>  YOU'RE LOOKING LIVE THERE,
NEWTOWN HIGH SCHOOL, THE GUYS
WALKING IN THERE, FIRST
RESPONDERS, STANDING OVATION
FOR SOME OF THE NEWTOWN
POLICE, THE FIREMEN, WALKING
INTO THE AUDITORIUM THERE,
BEFORE THE PRAYER SERVICE
STARTS.
YOU CAN SEE SOME OF THEM,
WIPING THE FOREHEAD.
IMAGINE SOME OF THE FIRST
RESPONDERS, GETTING TO THAT
SCENE, HAVING TO SECURE IT,
DEAL WITH THE SHOCK, DEAL WITH
THE SHOOTER STILL ON THE LOOSE
NOT KNOWING THE SITUATION AND
SEEING THE GRISLY SCENE IN
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE'RE AWAITING PRESIDENT OBAMA
TO ENTER THAT AUDITORIUM.
AS WE DO, IT'S JUST MINUTES
AWAY, LET'S BRING BACK OUR
PANEL, SENIOR WRITER FOR THE
WEEKLY STANDARD, STEVEN HAYES,
KIRSTEN POWERS, AND SYNDICATED
COLUMNIST CHARLES KRAUTHAMMER,
CONTRIBUTORS ALL.
WE'RE TALKING, CHARLES, WHAT
THIS MEANS TONIGHT, WHAT THE
PRESIDENT PERHAPS NEEDS TO DO,
WHAT HE MAY WANT TO DO TONIGHT
BEFORE THIS CROWD.
>> I THINK HIS JOB, REALLY, IS
TO LET THE PEOPLE KNOW, HAVE
SUFFERED AND CONTINUED TO
SUFFER THAT THE NATION SUFFERS
WITH THEM OF THE THAT'S HIS
ROLE, THAT'S HIS JOB.
IT'S NOT HIM AS PRESIDENT, HE
SPEAKS ON BEHALF OF THE
STATION, AS YOU SAID, SO THEY
UNDERSTAND HOW MUCH THE GRIEF
IS SHARED AND I MEAN, IT'S --
THERE'S NEVER ANY ULTIMATE
CONSOLATION, BUT THERE'S A
MODICUM OF IT, AND THE GRIEF
THAT WE SHARE AP SO MANY
OTHERS, IN FACT, A GREAT
NATION IS MOURNING AT THE SAME
TIME.
>> THE FAMILIES HAD FILED IN
AND INTO OUR DESIGNATED
RESERVED SEATS EARLIER, NINA,
AND REALLY, MEETING WITH THEM
HAD A SPECIAL PRIVATE TIME,
BUT THE MESSAGE IS REALLY TO
THE WHOLE COMMUNITY AND TO THE
NATION TONIGHT.
>> AND HE WAS DELAYED, AS WE
SAW, IN BEATING WITH THOSE
FAMILIES.
I'M SURE IT MUST HAVE BEEN
INCREDIBLY DIFFICULT AND HE'S
HAD TO DO IT IN THE SHOOTINGS,
WE TALKED ABOUT EARLIER, IN
THE ARIZONA CASE AND RECENTLY
IN THE AURORA, COLORADO
THEATER SHOOTING, BUT, YEAH,
THAT'S A PART OF HIS JOB AS
OUR CONSOLER IN CHIEF TONIGHT
IS TO PERSONALLY CONSOLE THE
FAMILIES AND TO PERSONALLY
TELL THEM THAT WE, AS A
NATION, GRIEVE WITH THEM, AS
WELL AS STEPPING TO THE
PODIUM.
>> Bret: ONE OF THE OF THE
THINGS THESE SHOOTINGS HAVE
DONE IS FOCUS EVERYONE'S
ATTENTION, KIRSTEN, SO MANY OF
THEM, AS YOU GO THROUGH THE
LIST AND YOU SEE HOW MANY
THERE HAVE BEEN.
WE FORGET, ALSO THE OTHER
SHOOTINGS.
THERE WAS A SHOOTER ON THE
LOOSE HERE IN D.C. THAT
DOMINATED EVERYTHING.
WE WERE CONSUMED IN WASHINGTON
D.C. WITH GOING TO A GAS
STATION, TAKING YOUR KIDS OUT
TO THE HOME DEPOT.
>> YES.
>> Bret: AND YOU THINK ABOUT
COMMUNITIES THAT ARE GRIPPED
WITH FEAR AFTER ONE OF THESE
EVENTS.
>> WELL, I THINK AS YOU'RE
SAYING, HE'S NOT JUST SPEAKING
TO THIS CROWD HERE, HE'S
SPEAKING TO THE NATION, A
NATION WHO IS MOURNING AND A
NATION WHO IS FRIGHTENED AND
PEOPLE WHO HAVE YOUNG CHILDREN
AND NIECES AND NEPHEWS, LOOK,
THEY SEE THIS AND THEY THINK
THIS COULD HAPPEN TO MY
CHILDREN.
I MEAN, WHAT'S TO SAY THERE'S
NOT A COPY CAT OR SOMETHING
LIKE THAT, AND I THINK THAT
THE PRESIDENT HAS TO -- IS
GOING TO BE DOING A LOT OF
REASSURING AS WELL.
>> WE'RE LOOKING LIVE AT THE
AUDITORIUM AT NEWTOWN HIGH
SCHOOL, ABOUT 900 PEOPLE
INSIDE THAT AUDITORIUM, ABOUT
1300 PEOPLE IN AN OVERFLOW
AREA THAT HAS A LIVE FEED.
THERE ARE OTHER PEOPLE
OUTSIDE.
WE'RE TOLD THE PLACE IS PACKED
AND OBVIOUSLY, A LOT OF FAMILY
MEMBERS THERE TO SEE THE
PRESIDENT, TO LISTEN TO HIM.
THERE'S A LONG LINEUP HERE AND
WE'RE GOING TO PAUSE NOW SO
THAT SOME OF OUR FOX STATIONS
AROUND THE COUNTRY COULD JOIN
US IN OUR COVERAGE.
A SOMBER DAY IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT AS PRESIDENT OBAMA
AND THE NATION JOIN THE PEOPLE
OF THAT COMMUNITY IN MOURNING.
GOOD EVENING FROM WASHINGTON,
I'M BRET BAIER.
THE SERVICE IN NEWTOWN, JUST
ABOUT TO GET STARTED,
REMEMBERING THE 26 PEOPLE
GUNNED DOWN IN THAT SCHOOL
FRIDAY MORNING, MOST OF THEM
CHILDREN.
WE'RE TOLD THAT BEFORE THE
VIGIL, THE PRESIDENT MET WITH
FAMILY MEMBERS AS WELL AS
FIRST RESPONDERS.
THIS ACUMENICAL WILL HAVE SONG
BEFORE THE PRESIDENT SPEAKS
AND THE PRESIDENT IS THE
PRIMARY ECH
WE'LL HEAR TONIGHT.
THIS AUDITORIUM FILLED WITH
FAMILY MEMBERS,  FIRST
RESPONDERS.
LET'S LISTEN THIS AS THE PIANO
MUSIC STARTS BEFORE THE
PRESIDENT WALKS IN.
♪
>>  AS WE WAIT FOR THE
PRESIDENT TO ARRIVE.
LET'S BRING IN OUR PANEL.
SENIOR WRITER FOR THE WEEKLY
STANDARD, STEVEN HAYES,
KIRSTEN POWERS, NINA EASTON
AND CHARLES KRAUTHAMMER.
AND STEVEN, WE TALKED ABOUT
WHAT THE PRESIDENT WANTS TO DO
TONIGHT.
>> I THINK HIS MAIN MESSAGE IS
TO COMMUNICATE TO THE PEOPLE
ACROSS THE COUNTRY THAT WE'RE
ALTOGETHER IN THIS.
THAT WE'RE WITH THE PEOPLE IN
NEWTOWN, THAT WE'RE THINKING
ABOUT YOU, WE'RE PRAYING
ALONGSIDE YOU.
HE REALLY DOES HAVE TO BE THE
CONSOLER IN CHIEF.
WHILE IT DOES SEEM ODD TO SAY
IT THIS EARLY BECAUSE THE PAIN
IS SO RAW AND SO FRESH, IT'S
INEVITABLE THAT THIS SERVICE
WILL PROBABLY BE THE FIRST
STEP IN WHAT WILL BE A LONG
AND INCREDIBLY DIFFICULT
RECOVERY PROCESS AND THE
PRESIDENT'S JOB IN SOME WAYS
IS TO BEGIN THAT PROCESS WITH
WORDS OF HEALING ALONG WITH
LEADING CLERGYMEN, CLERGY
FOLKS WITH HIM TONIGHT.
>> Bret: CHARLES, WE'VE HEARD
FROM ED HENRY THAT THIS WILL
NOT BE A POLICY SPEECH, THAT
THIS WILL BE A CONSOLING
SPEECH, THIS WILL BE A UNITING
SPEECH.
WE HEARD A LOT ON THE SUNDAY
SHOWS, ABOUT POLICY
PROJECTIONS GOING FORWARD, BUT
NOT TONIGHT.
>> NOT TONIGHT, BUT I DO THINK
THAT THIS EVENT IS LIKELY TO
BE A WATERSHED, I MEAN, IT'S
HARD TO PREDICT THESE THINGS
BECAUSE WE'RE ALL CAUGHT UP IN
THE EMOTION, BUT THE FREQUENCY
OF THESE ATTACKS AND FINALLY,
THE NATURE OF THIS ONE, IN THE
SAME WAY THAT 9/11 WOKE US UP
TO TERRORISM AFTER YEARS,
DECADES OF BEING ATTACKED
BECAUSE OF THE SHEER
MAGNITUDE, THIS ONE, I THINK,
WILL MAKE A MAGNITUDE BECAUSE
OF THE SHEER INNOCENCE OF THE
VICTIMS.
IN ARIZONA THE PRESIDENT IN
THE SPEECH TALKED ABOUT RISING
TO A HIGHER LEVEL OF CIVIL
DISCOURSE AND THE VEHICLE HE
USED TO MAKE THAT POINT WAS
THE NINE-YEAR-OLD GIRL WHO
DIED IN THAT ATTACK.
SHE WOULD HAVE WANTED US TO
CONDUCT OURSELVES IN A BETTER
WAY.
AND IT WAS IN THAT CASE WAS
ONLY A SINGLE CHILD.
HERE IT IS ESSENTIALLY, YOU
KNOW, A WHOLE CLASSROOM FULL
OF UTTERLY INNOCENT CHANGE AND
IN THE LANGUAGE, MEN, WOMEN
AND CHILDREN, NOTHING SPECIAL
ABOUT THE INNOCENCE--
IN SOME WAY ALL THE VICTIMS
ARE INNOCENT, BUT SUDDENLY
TRANSCENDENTLY, IT'S ABOUT
CHILDREN.
I THINK THAT MAY MAKE THE
DIFFERENCE AND I THINK THE
BEST COURSE IS THE ONE THAT
LIEBERMAN SUGGESTED NOT RASH
ACTION AND NOT BUSINESS AS
USUAL, BUT A COMMISSION THAT
WILL LOOK AT THIS, BRING IN
STUDIES AND BRING IN SOCIAL
SCIENTISTS AND HAVE
CONCLUSIONS THE WAY AS 9/11.
>> Bret: WE'LL CONTINUE WITH
THE PANEL IN A MOMENT, BUT ED
HENRY STANDING OUTSIDE THE
SCHOOL.
ED, I WANT TO CHECK IN WITH
YOU.
>> GOOD TO SEE YOU, BRET.
AS YOU KNOW, WHAT HAS BEEN A
SLIGHT DELAY TO THE START OF
THIS PROGRAM, THE PRESIDENT
WAS GOING THROUGH THE GRIM
TASK OF GREETING EACH FAMILY
OF THE 26 VICTIMS IN DIFFERENT
CLASSROOMS SET OUT ON THE HIGH
SCHOOL BEHIND ME, TRYING TO
SPEND SOME PERSONAL TIME WITH
EACH OF THEM, AN AS THE PANEL
HAS BEEN SAYING, TO START THE
GRIEVING PROCESS, START THE
HEALING PROCESS AS THEY MOVE
FORWARD HERE.
I WILL NOTE IT IS VERY CHILLY
OUT HERE, IT'S BEEN GETTING
CHILLIER AS THE NIGHT WEARS ON
AND YET, THERE HAVE BEEN A LOT
OF PEOPLE LINED UP OUTSIDE AND
I NOW SEE SOME PEOPLE LEAVING
BEHIND ME WE BELIEVE COULD NOT
GET IN BECAUSE YOU SAID, IT'S
ALREADY AT CAPACITY IN THAT
AUDITORIUM.
ONE WOMAN JUST IN THE LAST
FIVE OR TEN MINUTES WALKED BY
AND SHE WAS STILL HEADED IN,
SHE DIDN'T REALIZE IT WAS
ALREADY FULL AND SHE WAS WITH
A FRIEND AND I ASKED THEM HOW
LONG IT TOOK THEM TO GET HERE
BECAUSE THE CARS ARE LINED UP.
THERE'S NO MORE PARKING SPACES
NEAR THIS HIGH SCHOOL AND THE
TWO WOMEN SAID THEY WALKED ONE
HOUR IN THE RAIN, IN THE COLD,
JUST TO BE HERE, JUST TO REACH
OUT TO THE FELLOW MEMBERS OF
THIS COMMUNITY.
SO, IT GIVES YOU AN IDEA OF
THE DEPTH OF THE PAIN THAT
PEOPLE ARE FEELING, BUT ALSO,
THE DEPTH WITH WHICH THEY'RE
REACHING OUT TO TRY TO HELP
ONE ANOTHER THROUGH THIS
CRISIS, BRET.
>> Bret: THANK YOU, ON THE
STAGE 26 CANDLES IN GLASSES IN
FRONT OF THE PODIUM THERE.
26 CANDLES REPRESENTING THE 26
PEOPLE KILLED INSIDE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
20 OF THEM CHILDREN, AGES SIX
AND SEVEN YEARS OLD.
NINA EASTEN, FORTUNE MAGAZINE.
>> I THINK TO REMEMBER IT'S
NOT EVEN THE LARGEST MASS
MURDER AT A SCHOOL, VIRGINIA
TECH WAS, BUT THIS IS THE --
WE HOPE, AS CHARLES SAID, A
TIPPING POINT BECAUSE WHEN IT
INVOLVES SMALL CHILDREN, SIX
AND SEVEN YEAR OLDS, WHOSE
BODIES WERE RIDDLED WITH
BULLETS, RANGING FROM THREE TO
EIGHT--
THREE TO 11 WOUNDS PER CHILD,
IT'S SO HORRIFIC THAT IT
SHOULD BE TREATED AS A MOMENT
JUST LIKE 9/11 WAS, WE SHOULD
HAVE A CRISIS COMMISSION TO
LOOK AT THIS.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT THESE PAST
KILLINGS, THESE MASS KILLINGS,
BOTH FROM SCHOOLS AND OUTSIDE,
THERE'S A COUPLE OF THINGS
THAT STAND OUT FOR BEING IN
COMMON.
ONE IS THAT THERE WERE WARNING
SIGNS AND IT OFTEN INVOLVED
SOMEBODY WHO WAS EMOTIONALLY
UNSTABLE AND PEOPLE KNEW ABOUT
IT AND SECONDLY, IT INVOLVED
SEMI AUTOMATIC WEAPONS AND
RAISES THE DEATH TOLL AND
MAKES IT A MASS MURDER AS
OPPOSED TO A MURDER.
>> KIRSTEN.
>> WE HOPE IT'S A WATERSHED
MOMENTS, WE FOCUS ON THE
MOMENTS AND MOVE ON AND THE
PEOPLE WHO ARE MOST ENTRENCHED
ARE THE PEOPLE THAT ARGUE NO,
WE MUST HAVE SEMI AUTOMATIC
WEAPONS OR YOU CAN'T DO
ANYTHING TO LIMIT VIDEO GAMES.
YOU HAVE THESE PEOPLE WHO HAVE
SELF-INTEREST IN IT AND THEY
TEND TO DOMINATE.
WHAT MAKES THIS ONE, AS
CHARLES WAS SAYING, THEY WERE
INNOCENT, BUT THEY WERE
HELPLESS.
I THINK THAT'S ONE OF THE
MAJOR THINGS YOU OFTEN HEAR
PEOPLE SAYING, WELL, IF THE
PERSON HAD BEEN ARMED THEY
COULD HAVE DEFENDED
THEMSELVES.
WELL, THESE WERE THE MOST
HELPLESS PEOPLE IN THE WORLD
THESE LITTLE CHILDREN WHO
WOULDN'T KNOW, MAYBE THEY KNEW
TO RUN AWAY AT BEST, BUT YOU
KNOW, WHO REALLY LOOKED TO
ADULTS TO HELP THEM.
IF THIS ISN'T A WATERSHED
MOMENT THEN WE PROBABLY NEVER
WILL HAVE ONE SO I REALLY HOPE
THAT WE'LL SEE SOMETHING COME
OF THIS.
>> Bret: IT MAY ALSO BE A
WATERSHED MOMENT, STEVE, ON
THE MENTAL ILLNESS SIDE OF THE
COIN.
WE HAVEN'T TALKED A LOT ABOUT
THAT AS A NATION.
BUT SOME PEOPLE TODAY ARE
TALKING ABOUT THAT A LOT MORE
THAN THEY EVER HAVE.
>> WELL, IF WE DO HAVE THAT
KIND OF BROAD COMMISSION TAKE
A LOOK AT THIS AND SAY, LOOK,
NORMALLY I'M SKEPTICAL OF
THESE KINDS OF COMMISSIONS
COMING OUT OF WASHINGTON,
THEY'RE AN EXCUSE NOT TO GET
SOMETHING DONE RATHER THAN TO
HAVE A SERIOUS CONVERSATION
ABOUT IMPORTANT ISSUES, BUT I
THINK IN THIS CASE WE COULD
HAVE THAT KIND OF CONVERSATION
POTENTIALLY, THROUGH A
COMMISSION, BUT IT WOULD HAVE
TO INCLUDE THOSE KINDS OF
ISSUES, I MEAN, WE'VE SEEN AS
WE'VE DISCUSSED A LITTLE BIT
EARLIER, AGAIN AND AGAIN AND
AGAIN, SIGNS AND WARNINGS
REPEATEDLY AGAIN AND AGAIN,
PEOPLE, PARENTS WHO HAVE CRIED
OUT AND SAID THAT THEY WANT
ASSISTANCE, THAT THEY WANT
HELP AND UNABLE TO GET IT.
THAT HAS TO BE PART OF THIS
DISCUSSION, PARTICULARLY IF WE
LEARN MORE ABOUT ADAM LANZA
AND THE PROBLEMS THAT HE MAY
HAVE HAD.
>> CHARLES?
>> I THINK IF YOU PUT
LIEBERMAN AND RUDY GUILIANI IN
CHARGE, YOU MIGHT GET A
COMMISSION THAT ACTUALLY DOES
SOMETHING AND EVERYTHING HAS
TO BE ON THE TABLE, ALL THE
THREE ELEMENTS.
I MEAN, FOR 30 YEARS EVER
MENTALLY ILL, NOT OVER THERE,
BUT BECAUSE OF THE HOMELESS
MAJORITY OF WHICH ARE MENTALLY
ILL, THEY'RE NOT DESTITUTE AND
WE LEAVE THEM TO DIE IN THE
COLD WITH THEIR RIGHTS ON.
AND OF COURSE I'VE BEEN
TALKING IN THE THE WIND ALL OF
THESE YEARS, BUT THERE'S A
CHANGE IN OUR ATTITUDE WITH
COMMITMENT AND ABUSE OF THAT
IN THE 50'S, BUT THERE'S GOT
TO BE LOOKING AT THAT AS WELL
AS THE OTHER ELEMENTS.
AS I SAID IT'S GOING TO
IMPINGE ON THE FIRST
AMENDMENT, GOING TO IMPINGE ON
THE SECOND, GOING TO IMPINGE
ON THE FIFTH.
THAT'S A LOT OF IMPINGING, BUT
OUR COUNTRY MIGHT BE READY FOR
THAT HOW TO DEAL WITH A MASS
KILLINGS IN AN OPEN SOCIETY.
>> Bret: WE'VE BEEN JUST GIVEN
UNDER TWO MINUTE WARNING AND
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND THE
OFFICIAL START OF THIS PRAYER
SERVICE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THIS IS THE NEWTOWN HIGH
SCHOOL.
THIS IS WHERE WE WILL BE
SEEING THE PRESIDENT SPEAK FOR
THE NATION, REMEMBERING THE 26
PEOPLE KILLED, SHOT AND KILLED
IN SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
27 KILLED, INCLUDING THE
MOTHER OF THE SHOOTER.
28 THE SHOOTER KILLED HIMSELF.
ED HENRY IS OUTSIDE.
ED?
>> Reporter: BRET, WE'RE
TALKING TO MORE PEOPLE WHO
AGAIN, UNFORTUNATELY, CAN'T
GET IN BECAUSE, YOU KNOW, IT'S
JUST AT CAPACITY.
BUT WHILE THEY'RE
DISAPPOINTED, THEY UNDERSTAND
THE SITUATION AND SUPPOSED
JUST SPOKE TO, FROM THE SIKH
COMMUNITY, NOT HERE, BOSTON A
LONG DRIVE AWAY AND ONE WOMAN
FROM THAT WE TALKED TO, SAID
THERE'S A CONNECTION, THE SIKH
TEMPLE.
AND THEY WANTED TO BE HERE AND
EXPLAINED TO US JUST A MOMENT
AGO, GETTING TEARY-EYED
TALKING ABOUT HOW SHE AND HER
FAMILY WANTED TO BE HERE FOR
THIS COMMUNITY.
SO EXACTLY WHAT YOU'RE TALKING
ABOUT, PEOPLE WHO HAVE SEEN
ENOUGH OF THESE GO BY,
STANDING UP AND SAYING THEY
WANT TO STAND TOGETHER AND
FIGURE THIS OUT.
>> Bret: YOU'VE BEEN THERE NOW
FOR THE DAY AND JUST
ENCAPSULATE SOME OF THE
EMOTION IN JUST TALKING TO
PEOPLE OUT THERE?
>> Reporter: THE BIGGEST THING
I'VE SEEN, I'VE BEEN STUNNED
AND ACTUALLY HAVEN'T SEEN A
LOT OF PEOPLE AND THEY'RE JUST
WALKING BY SO I DON'T WANT TO
OVERSTATE IT, BUT I DON'T SEE
A LOT OF PEOPLE CRYING OR
SCREAMING OUT IN PAIN.
OBVIOUSLY, THE FAMILIES HAVE
GONE THROUGH THIS OVER THE
LAST 24 HOURS SO THE PEOPLE IN
THIS COMMUNITY LOOK
DETERMINED, LOOK LIKE THEY'RE
OUT HERE IN THE COLD BECAUSE
THEY WANT TO BE HERE FOR THEIR
FELLOW CITIZENS AND WHEN I'VE
TALKED TO THEM, THEY'VE SAID
THINGS LIKE I KNEW A TEACHER
WHO WAS KILLED.
AND ANOTHER GENTLEMAN SAID HE
KNEW THE PRINCIPAL WHO WE'VE
LEARNED ABOUT WHO WAS SO
HEROIC AND PUT HERSELF IN THE
LINE OF FIRE TO SAVE OTHER
LIVES AND THAT'S WHAT I'M
SEEING TONIGHT.
>> Bret: ED HENRY, THANK YOU.
THE PRESIDENT HAS JUST ENTERED
THE ROOM.
PRESIDENT OBAMA, AT NEWTOWN
HIGH SCHOOL, WHERE THIS PRAYER
SERVICE TO REMEMBER THE
VICTIMS OF THE NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTING.
LET'S LISTEN IN.
>> ON BEHALF OF THE NEWTOWN
INTERFAITH CLERGY ASSOCIATION,
I WELCOME ALL OF YOU.
WE NEEDED THIS.
WE NEEDED TO BE TOGETHER HERE
IN THIS ROOM, IN THE
GYMNASIUM, OUTSIDE THE DOORS
OF THIS SCHOOL IN LIVING ROOMS
AROUND THE WORLD.
WE NEEDED TO BE TOGETHER, TO
SHOW THAT WE ARE TOGETHER AND
UNIT
UNITED.
WE GATHER IN SUCH A MOMENT OF
HEART BREAK FOR ALL OF US HERE
IN NEWTOWN.
WE GATHER ESPECIALLY MINDFUL
OF FAMILY AND FRIENDS AND
NEIGHBORS AMONG US WHO HAVE
LOST LOVED ONES BY AN ACT OF
UNFATHOMABLE VIOLENCE AND
DESTRUCTION.
WE GATHER TO GRIEVE TOGETHER
TO CARE FOR ONE ANOTHER, TO
PRAY AND EMBRACE, TO WEEP AND
TO REMEMBER AND TO DECLARE IN
OUR MANY VOICES THAT THESE
DARKEST DAYS OF OUR COMMUNITY
SHALL NOT BE THE FINAL WORLD
HEARD FROM US.
WE WILL SIGH IN OUR SORROWS,
BUT WE WILL ALSO CARE FOR ONE
ANOTHER WITH OUR LOVE AND OUR
COMPASSION.
IN THOSE EARLY HOURS OF THIS
CRISIS IT BECAME CLEAR TO WE
CLERGY AND FAITH LEADERS HERE
IN NEWTOWN THAT INITIAL, AN
INITIAL COMMUNITY RESPONSE
WOULD BE NEEDED, THAT WE WOULD
NEED TO COME TOGETHER AND SO,
WE ASKED OUR FIRST SELECT
WOMAN AND OUR SUPERINTENDENT
IF IT MIGHT BE POSSIBLE FOR US
CLERGY TO INVITE THE COMMUNITY
TO GATHER HERE AT NEWTOWN HIGH
SCHOOL TO CONTINUE AND TO
BEGIN AND TO CONTINUE WHAT
WILL BE FOR MANY A LONG
JOURNEY THROUGH GRIEF AND
LOSS.
WE ARE NOT HERE TO IGNORE OUR
DIFFERENCES OR TO DIMINISH THE
CORE BELIEFS WHICH DEFINE OUR
MANY DIFFERENCE IN TRADITIONS,
BUT TO OFFER OUR LOVE, CARE
AND PRAYERS FOR OUR FAMILIES
AND OUR COMMUNITY.
WE WANTED TO OFFER OUR VOICES
IN THE FORM OF WORDS FROM OUR
SACRED TEXTS AND PRAYERS FROM
THE DEPTHS OF OUR BEING, BUT
ALSO TO HAVE TIME FOR US TO BE
TOGETHER IN SILENCE.
AND THAT IS WHAT WE WILL DO.
WE WILL HAVE A TIME FOR
SHARING AND PRAYER AND ALSO A
TIME FOR SILENCE IN BETWEEN SO
THAT ALL OF US CAN PRAY AS WE
WISH AND THINK ABOUT WHAT IT
IS THAT IS MOST IMPORTANT TO
US.
NOW, THERE'S A REASON WHY ALL
OF THE CLERGY ARE SITTING DOWN
THERE AND NOT UP HERE.
AND WE HOPE YOU DON'T GET
TIRED OF SEEING US HAVE THE
LONG WALK UP TO THIS PODIUM,
BUT WE WANTED TO BE -- TO HAVE
A SYMBOLIC GESTURE THAT WE
OURSELVES ARE WITH YOU AND
AMONG YOU IN THESE COMING
DAYS.
THAT WE ARE ALL IN THIS
TOGETHER.
WE WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT OUR
CARE FOR THIS COMMUNITY
EXTENDS BEYOND THE WALLS OF
OUR VARIOUS HOUSES OF WORSHIP
AND THE PEOPLE WITHIN THEM.
WE ARE HERE FOR ALL OF
NEWTOWN.
THAT MEANS THAT YOU WHO ARE OF
ST. ROSE CATHOLIC CHURCH, IN
THE MIDST OF YOUR TREMENDOUS
GRIEF THERE IS A JEWISH RABBI
WITH A TORA IN HAND READY TO
SPEAK WORDS OF COMFORT AND DO
WHATEVER HE CAN TO UPHOLD YOU
IN THE COMING DAYS.
AND AT TEMPLE ISRAEL YOU HAVE
A SERVICE OF A JAPANESE
AMERICAN MINISTER READY TO
PRAY WITH YOU AND WITH SONGS
FROM JOHN WESLEY.
>> AND CONVERSATION WITH
UCCARS KNOW THAT WE HAVE
MUSLIM BROTHERS AND SISTERS
READY TO OFFER PRAYERS OF
COMPASSION AND PENTECOSTALS
READY TO PRAY WITH
EPISCOPALIANS AND LUTHREN
MINISTRIES OFFERING GRACE IN
JESUS CHRIST TO OTHERS TO
RECEIVE COMFORT AND SUPPORT
FROM THOSE OF NO FAITH.
YOU SEE, NOW MORE THAN EVER,
WE NEED EACH OTHER FOR WE ARE
ALL IN THIS TOGETHER.
THAT'S WHY WE EVEN HAVE OUR
POLITICIANS SIT DOWN THERE AS
WELL.
A SIGN AND SYMBOL AND REMINDER
TO ALL OF US THAT WE ARE IN
THIS TOGETHER.
SO NOW, LET US COME TOGETHER.
LET US PRAY.
LET US LISTEN AND LET US SEEK
COMFORT OF OUR VARIOUS FAITHS,
DRAWING FROM WORDS AND PRAYE
PRAYERS.
FEAR NOT FOR I AM WITH YOU.
BE NOT DISMAYED FOR I AM YOUR
GOD.
I WILL STRENGTHEN YOU.
I WILL UPHOLD YOU WITH MY
VICTORIOUS HAND.
GOD IS WITH US.  OVE UNITES US.
GOD'S PURPOSE STEADIES US.
GOD'S SPIRIT COMFORTS US.
LET BE OUR GOD FOREVER AND
EVER, AMEN.
>>  I OFFER YOU THIS PRAYER
FROM MY HEART TO YOUR HEART,
ON BEHALF OF ALL OF YOUR
CHILDREN, ALL OF YOUR LOVED
ONES.
THE HEBREW MEMORIAL PRAYER.
PLEASE RISE.
♪
.
[SINGING PRAYER]
♪
.
[SINGING PRAYER]
♪