>> GOOD MORNING EVERYONE.
HAPPY FRIDAY.
>> I AM HEATHER NAUERT.
>> I AM HEATHER CHILDERS.
THANK YOU FOR WATCHING FOX AND
FRIENDS FIRST.
>>> TIME FOR YOUR 5@5:00.
THE TOP FIVE MAKING NEWS FOR YOU
AT THIS HOUR.
WE ARE 18 DAYS AWAY FROM GOING
OVER THE FISCAL CLIFF.
THE PRESIDENT AND HOUSE SPEAKER
JOHN BOEHNER HARD AT WORK TRYING
TO AVOID THE ECONOMIC DISASTER.
THE TWO MET FOR ABOUT 50 MINUTES
TO MAKE PROGRESS TOWARD A DEAL.
NEITHER SIDE WOULD GO INTO
DETAIL ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED.
BOEHNER CRITICIZED THE PRESIDENT
FOR UNWILLINGNESS TO COMPROMISE.
>> THE PRESIDENT PROMISED
BALANCED APPROACH HIS PROPOSALS
HAVE BEEN ANYTHING BUT.
HE WANTS FAR MORE IN TAX HIKES
THAN IN SPENDING CUTS.
>> AFTER LATE DAY MEETING
BOEHNER SAID TALKS WERE QUOTE
DOING GREAT.
>> NEW DETAILS EMERGING ABOUT
THE MAN WHO OPENED FIRE INSIDE
THE CROWDED MALL IN OREGON.
JACOB ROBERTS ROOMMATE SAYS HE
HAD A WEIRD LOOK ON HIS FACE
WHEN HE LEFT THE HOUSE.
ROBERTS APPARENTLY WANTED TO
JOIN THE MARINES.
A FOOT INJURY KEPT HIM FROM
DOING THAT.
HE SHOT AND KILLED TWO PEOPLE
INSIDE OF A MALL ON THURSDAY
BEFORE HE TURNED THE GUN ON
HIMSELF.
A 15-YEAR-OLD VICTIM STILL
REMAINS IN THE HOSPITAL IN
SERIOUS CONDITION.
THE MALL IS SET TO REOPEN LATER
TODAY.
>>> THIS IS A TROUBLING STORY
MED AF WILL HONOR RECIPIENT
BRUTALLY ATTACKED IN AN EVENT
OVER THE WEEKEND.
POLICE ARRESTED AND CHARGED AN
18-YEAR-OLD.
MEYER IS RECOVERING AFTER THE
ATTACK.
HE WAS AWARDED THE MILITARY'S
HIGHEST HONOR BY PRESIDENT OBAMA
LAST YEAR.
HE IS CREDITED OF SAVING THE
LIVES OF 13 AMERICANS AND 23
AFGHAN SOLDIERS DURING A
FIREFIGHT IN 2009.
HE WAS THE FIRST LIVING MARINE
TO RECEIVE THE AWARD IN NEARLY
THREE DECADES.
>> LEON PINEDA HAS AGREED TO
SEND 2 PATRIOT MISSILES 400
TROOPS TO THE COUNTRY IN ORDER
TO BEEF UP THE COUNTRY'S
DEFENSES IN THE SYRIAN ATTACKS.
TH
GERMANY WILL SEND TWO MUSCLES
EACH.
ALL 6 PATRIOT MISSILES WILL BE
UNDER NATO CONTROL AND SHOULD BE
OPERATIONAL BY JANUARY.
>> SPECIAL NIGHT AT THE WHITE
HOUSE AND PRESIDENT OBAMA AND
THE FIRST LADY CELEBRATED THE
6TH NIGHT OF HANUKKAH.
IT INCLUDED TRADITIONAL PRAYERS
AND THE LIGHTING OF CANDLES FROM
A 90-YEAR-OLD MENORAH.
IT WAS SERIOUSLY DAMAGED SUPER
HE STORM SANDY.
IT SYMBOLIZES PERSEVERANCE MUCH
LIKE THE HOLIDAY.
>> JEWS HONOR EVER LASTING HOPE
THAT LIGHT WILL OVER COME THE
DARKNESS, GOODNESS OVER COMES
EVIL AND FAITH CAN ACCOMPLISH
MIRACLES.
>>> THE PRESIDENT ALSO
AMERICA'S SUPPORT FOR ISRAEL
REMAINS UNSHAKEABLE.
THAT IS YOUR 5@5:00.
>> ENDING IT BEFORE IT EVEN
STARTED U.N. AMBASSADOR SUSAN
RICE TAKING HER NAME OUT OF
RUNNING FOR THE SECRETARY OF
STATE POSITION.
THIS FOLLOWING MONTHS OF
CRITICISM OVER HER COMMENTS ON
THE BENGHAZI ATTACK.
PETER DOOCY IS FOLLOWING THIS
STORY FROM WASHINGTON AND THERE
ARE SO MANY ANGLES TO THIS ONE.
GOOD MORNING, PETER.
>> THERE ARE.
AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE WAS NEVER
ACTUALLY NOMINATED FOR THE JOB
OF SECRETARY OF STATE BUT BASED
ON STATEMENTS PRESIDENT OBAMA
MADE IN PUBLIC HEFZ BELIEVED TO
BE A FRONTRUNNER FOR HIS
NOMINATION.
SHE THINKS A POTENTIAL
CONFIRMATION PROCESS WOULD HAVE
BEEN LENGTHY AND DISRUPTIVE SO
SHE SAYS SHE IS OUT.
>> I WITHDREW MY NAME BECAUSE I
THINK IT'S THE RIGHT THING FOR
THE COUNTRY.
I THINK IT'S THE RIGHT THING FOR
THE PRESIDENT AND PUTTING THOSE
THINGS TOGETHER THAT MAKES IT
THE RIGHT THING FOR ME AND MY
FAMILY.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID WHILE I
DEEPLY REGRET THE UNFAIR ATTACKS
ON SUSAN RICE IN RECENT WEEKS
THE POSITION DEMONSTRATES
STRENGTH OF HER CHARACTER AND
ADMIRABLE COMMITMENT TO RISE
ABOVE THE POLITICS AT THE MOMENT
TO PUT OUR NATIONAL INTERESTS
FIST.
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE CAN BE PROUD
TO HAVE A PUBLIC SERVANT OF HER
CALIBER AND CHARACTER
REPRESENTING OUR COUNTRY.
REPUBLICAN SENATOR LINDSAY
GRAHAM SAYS HE RESPECTS RICE'S
DECISION TO WITHDRAW HER NAME.
GRAHAM HAS BEEN HIGHLY CRITICAL
OF RICE AND HER ROLE IN THE
ADMINISTRATION'S PUBLIC RESPONSE
TO THE TERROR ATTACK IN
BENGHAZI.
MEANWHILE FORMER U.S. AMBASSADOR
TO THE SNUCHLT JOHN BOLTON
EXPLAINS WHY HE THINKS ALL OF
THIS SUSPECT HAD AING.
>> I THINK THEY HAD COME TO A
POLITICAL CONCLUSION IT WAS TOO
COSTLY FOR THE NOMINATION TO GO
FORWARD AND SHE WANTED TO GET
HER $0.02 ON THAT.
I WOULDN'T BE SURPRISED AFTER A
FEW FRIENDLY INTERVIEWS THERE IS
MORE DISCUSSION ABOUT IT.
I THINK THE ADMINISTRATION WANTS
TO GET THIS OFF THE RADAR
SCREEN.
>>> MASSACHUSETTS DEMOCRATIC
SENATOR JOHN KERRY IS NOW
BELIEVED TO BE PRESIDENT OBAMA'S
TOP CHOICE TO REPLACE HILLARY
CLINTON AND SECRETARY OF STATE.
DON'T EXPECT AMBASSADOR TORE
RICE TO DISPIER.
SHE IS BEING MENTIONED AS A PICK
FOR NATIONAL SECURITY ADVISOR A
VERY IMPORTANT JOB THAT DOES NOT
REQUIRE SENATE CONFIRMATION AND
IT IS ON THE SCHEDULE TO MEET
WITH PRESIDENT OBAMA LATER ON
TODAY.
HEATHER?
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
NO SENATE CONFIRMATION.
THAT MIGHT BE KEY.
NOW IT IS TIME FOR A LOOK AT WHO
IS TALKING.
>> CHARLES KRAUTHAMMER LOOKING
AT HIS REASON WHY HE BELIEVES
RICE HEYED THE DECISION.
>> HAD SHE BEEN NOMINATED
BENGHAZI SCANDAL ABOVE BEEN ON
THE FRONT PAGE.
WITH HER NOT BEING NOMINATED
BENGHAZI SCANDAL WILL DIE IN THE
MAINSTREAM MEDIA THEY WILL HAVE
NO INTEREST IN THE STORY.
THAT'S WHY I THINK THE PRESIDENT
PUT HIMSELF OUT THERE HE WOULD
RATHER HAVE HAD HER I THINK HE
FEELS HE SOMEHOW KNEELEDED AND
HER CONSOLATION WILL BE HE WILL
MAKE HER NATIONAL SECURITY
ADVISOR WHICH IS A VERY POWERFUL
POSITION WHICH DOES NOT REQUIRE
THE AS SENT OF THE SENATE.
>> JOHN KERRY IS ANOTHER RUMORED
CHOICE TO REPLACE HILLARY
CLINTON AS SECRETARY OF STATE.
FOX POLL SHOWS WHAT AMERICANS
THINK ABOUT KERRY AND RICE.
>> WHEN ASKED WHO PRESIDENT
OBAMA SHOULD NOMINATE AS THE
NEXT SECRETARY OF STATE WHEN
GIVEN A CHOICE BETWEEN KERRY AND
RICE THE MAJORITY 37 PERCENT
SAID SOMEONE ELSE.
KERRY RECEIVING 23 PERCENT WHILE
SUSAN RICE RECEIVED 19 PERCENT.
>>> KEEPING ON THE TOPIC OF P
BENGHAZI THE FOX NEWS POLL ASKED
THOSE POLLED THOUGHT THE
PRESIDENT SHOULD ORDER TROOPS TO
BENGHAZI TO HELP AMERICANS THERE
25 PERCENT SAID YES -- 65
PERCENT, 24 PERCENT NO AND THE
REST WERE UNSURE.
>>> DID THEY TRY TO COVER IT UP?
>> 47 PERCENT SAID YES WHILE 42
PERCENT SAID NO.
>>> ALL RIGHT.
LET'S TALK ABOUT SOME BUSINESS
NEWS NOW.
EVEN IF A LAST MINUTE DEAL IS
REACHED TO AVOID THE FISCAL
CLIFF THE DAMAGE MAY ALREADY BE
DONE BECAUSE A LOT OF SMALL
BUSINESS OWNERS WE HAVE TALKED
TO ARE NOT INVESTING IN THEIR
OWN BUSINESSES BECAUSE OF FEAR
OF GOING OVER THE EDGE.
YOU TALK TO ANY SMALL BUSINESS
OWNER IT'S UNCERTAINTY.
>> THE ELECTION WAS SUPPOSED TO
TAKE AWAY THAT UNCERTAINTY.
DIDN'T HAPPEN.
THE FISCAL CLIFF PARALYZED SO
MANY SMALL BUSINESSES.
THE BIG JOB CREATORS OUT THERE.
A WELLS FAR GO GALLUP SURVEY
FOUND THOSE SPENDING INTENTIONS
FALLEN TO A YEAR LOAD.
THEY ARE NOT UPGRADING COMPUTERS
OR HIRING WORKERS.
THE REASON IS THE FISCAL CLIFF.
SMALL FIRMS ARE SLOW COMPANIES
ARE S BE CORPSE SO THEY ARE
TAXED AS INDIVIDUALS AND LIKELY
MAKE 250,000 DOLLARS A YEAR
MEANING THEY WILL GET STUNG BY
HIGHER TAXES.
>> TALK TO US ABOUT TWITTER A
BIG YEAR FOR PRESIDENT OBAMA OF
COURSE NO SURPRISE THERE.
>> IT IS THE TIME OF YEAR WHEN
WE REFLECT ON WHAT HAPPENED
THROUGH OUT THE YEAR.
TWITTER IS A GREAT WAY TO
MEASURE A LOT OF THAT.
THE MOST RETWEETED MESSAGE OF
THE YEAR.
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S 4 YEAR VICTORY
TWEET WITH A PHOTO OF HIM
HUGGING THE FIRST LADY.
RIEPT BEHIND THE PRESIDENT
JUSTIN BIEBER A GOOD-BYE TWEET
TO A FRIEND WHO DIED OF BRAIN
CANCER.
>> A WHOLE LOT OF US ARE
TRAVELING FOR THE HOLIDAY SEASON
MORE THAN IN THE PAST 6 YEARS.
>> IT IS AT A HIGH.
BASICALLY GET READY FOR HOLIDAY
TRAFFIC JAMS.
AAA IS PREDICTING 93.3 MILLION
AMERICANS WILL HIT THE ROADS OR
THE SKIES THIS HOLIDAY SEASON.
THAT WOULD MAKE THE BUSIEST
TRAVEL SEASON IN 6 YEARS.
SPENDING COULD BE UP AS WELL
FORECAST TO INCREASE 6 PERCENT
TO $759.
WHY IS THAT?
WE ARE PROBABLY GOING OUT A LOT
MORE AND SPENDING MONEY ON
ENTERTAINMENT.
GET THIS?
GAS PRICES NOT EXPECTED TO RISE.
MAYBE 3.30 CENTS A GALLON BY THE
END OF THE YEAR.
AIR FAIR IS DOWN.
HOTEL RATES THRIVING A LITTLE
BIT ABOUT 2-3 PERCENT.
>> WE WILL CRASH ON THE FAMILY
MEMBER'S COUCH.
>> WITH THE HOLIDAY TRAVELS
THAT'S WHAT WE WANT YOU TO BREW
ON TODAY.
WE WANT TO KNOW IF YOU ARE
PLANNING TO TRAVEL FOR THE
HOLIDAYS IF SO WHERE YOU ARE
HEADED.
YOU CAN TWEET THEM TO US AT FOX
FRIENDS FIRST OR SHOOT US AN
E-MAIL AT FOX FRIEND FIRST AT
foxnews.com AND WE WILL READ
SOME OF THOSE LATER ON IN THE
SHOW.
>>> NOW IT IS TIME FOR YOUR
FIRST DEGREE WEATHER UPDATE WITH
JANICE DEAN.
WILL MOTHER NATURE COOPERATE FOR
TRAVELERS TODAY?
>> TRAVELERS ACROSS THE EAST
WILL BE IN GOOD SHAPE.
ACROSS THE WEST ANOTHER STORY.
CLEAR SKIES FOR MUCH OF THE
EASTERN HALF OF THE COUNTRY YOU
MOVE TO THE WEST WE HAVE STORM
SYSTEMS ONE ACROSS THE WEST
ANOTHER SOUTHWEST WITH A LOT OF
RAIN AND SNOW WHICH IS GREAT
NEWS FOR THE TRAVELERS.
18 INCHES FOR PARTS OF THE
MOUNTAINOUS REGIONS OF COLORADO
THROUGH ARIZONA UP THROUGH THE
ROCKY MOUNTAINS.
THIS IS MAINLY A GAD THING
BECAUSE A LOT OF COUNTRY IS INTO
A DROUGHT.
THIS SYSTEM IS GOING TO MOVE
INTO THE CENTRAL U.S. BY
SATURDAY AND THEN ACROSS THE
EAST COAST BY SUNDAY.
GOING TO GET RAIN ACROSS THE
SOUTHEAST AND SNOW ACROSS THE
SOUTHEAST.
THEY ARE MOVING ACROSS THE MAJOR
CITIES TODAY.
WE WILL GET INTO A LITTLE BIT OF
ACTIVITY.
>> I WAS LISTENING TO YOU.
>> THE TIME NOW IS 11 MINUTES
AFTER THE TOP OF THE HOUR.
A REAL SCROOGE TAKING AWAY THE
CHRISTMAS CONCERT REPLACING IT
WITH SOMETHING ELSE.
>> THE PARENTS PLEADING WITH THE
PRESIDENT'S HEALTH A SON
FIGHTING FOR HIS LIFE INSIDE OF
A MEXICAN PRISON.
>> IT HAS GONE ON TOO LONG.
IT'S A RIDICULOUS CASE.
I THINK THEY KNOW IT'S A
RIDICULOUS CASE.
I AM ASKING THE PRESIDENT TO GET
INVOLVED AT THIS POINT.
>> WE WILL HEAR MORE FROM THEM
AND THE LAWYER WHO IS WORKING
HARD TO FREE THEM.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THEY ARE A GLOWING EXAMPLE
OF WHAT IT MEANS TO BE
THE BEST.
AND AT THIS SPECIAL TIME
OF YEAR,
THEY SHINE EVEN BRIGHTER.
COME TO THE WINTER EVENT
AND GET THE MERCEDES-BENZ
YOU'VE ALWAYS WISHED FOR,
NOW FOR AN EXCEPTIONAL PRICE.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
GLK350 FOR $399 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
>> IT IS NOW QUARTER PAST THE
HOUR.
HERE'S WHAT YOU MISSED WHILE YOU
WERE SLEEPING.
THE RADIO HOSTS BEHIND THE HOAX
HAVE BEEN MOVE TO DO SAFE HOUSES
BECAUSE THEY RECEIVED DEATH
THREATS.
SEVERAL OTHER RADIO STAFFERS ARE
GIVEN 24-HOUR PROTECTION AS
WELL.
WE ARE LEARNING THE STATION MAY
ACTUALLY LOSE ITS LICENSE.
THOSE HOSTS ARE BEING BLAMED A
LOT OF FOLKS THAT THE REASON
KATE MIDDLETON'S NURSE TOOK HER
OWN LIFE.
A MEMORIAL SERVICE IS BEING HELD
IN HER HOME TOWN LATER TODAY.
>> COULD JENNI RIVERA STILL BE
ALIVE?
SHE TOOK THE LAST MINUTE
DECISION TO TAKE THE PLANE RIDE
EVEN THOUGH THEY OFFER TO DO PUT
HER UP IN A HOTEL ROOM FOR THE
NIGHT.
HEATHER?
>>> TYKE FOR A LOOK AT WHO IS
TALKING.
WE ARE HEARING FROM THE PARENTS
AND LAWYER OF THE FORMER MARINE
BEING HELD IN MEXICO ON GUN
CHARGES.
>> JOHN HAMMER JUNIOR WAS
ARRESTED WHIEFLZ PASSING THROUGH
A MEXICAN BORDER CITY ON THE WAY
TO COSTA RICA.
HE WAS ARRESTED FOR CARRYING
THIS ANTIQUE SHOT GUN.
IT BELONGED TO HIS GRANDFATHER.
A U.S. BORDER PATROL AGENT TOLD
HIM IT WAS LEGAL AS LONG AS HE
DECLARED IT WITH MEXICAN
AUTHORITIES.
WHEN HE WENT TO DO THAT HE WAS
ARRESTED INSTEAD.
>>> IN A MOMENT WE WILL HEAR HIS
PARENT'S PLEA TO PRESIDENT
OBAMA.
FIRST HERE'S HIS LAWYER'S
EXPLANATION OF THIS EVENT.
>> THE CUSTOMS TOLD HIM IT WAS
LEGAL TO GO TO MEXICO WITH
REGISTRATION PAPERS.
THE PROBLEM WAS WHEN HE CAME
BACK INTO THE STATES.
HE GOES THROUGH MEXICO WITH
CUSTOMS TOLD HIM TO WAIT AND
FOOI HOURS AFTER THEY RAISED HIM
FOR VIOLATION OF ARTICLE 11
PARAGRAPH H OF THE FEDERAL LAW
OF WEAPONS AND EXPLOSIVES WHICH
SAYS YOU CAN HAVE ANY SHOT GUN
EXCEPT CERTAIN TYPE OF SHOT GUNS
FOR EXAMPLE ONES OF CERTAIN
CALIBER.
THIS PARTICULAR CALIBER WAS .410
WHICH IS NOT -- IT IS NOT
RESERVED FOR EXCLUSIVE USE OF
THE ARMED FORCES AND NEITHER
WERE THE BULLETS THE GAUGES THAT
WAS FOR THE NONEXCLUSIVES.
THE ISSUE HERE REALLY IS THE
LENGTH OF THE BARREL.
THAT'S THE PROBLEM.
HOW IT WAS MEASURED AND ALSO
MOST IMPORTANT THAT IS WHY.
THIS HAD TO BE UNDER 25 INCHES
AND WE BELIEVE THE PRESSURE WAS
TAKEN THE WRONG WAY.
>> THERE HAN SOME CRITICISM HERE
AT HOME THAT THE STATE
DEPARTMENT AND THE
ADMINISTRATION ARE NOT DOING
ENOUGH TO HELP SECURE HAMMER'S
RELEASE.
LAST NIGHT HIS PARENTS SPOKE
WITH SEAN HANNITY ABOUT THIS
MAKING A PLEA TO PRESIDENT
OBAMA.
>> WE ARE JUST ASKING FOR
EVERYONE TO TALK TO THEIR
LAWMAKERS.
I WOULD MAKE A PERSONAL PLEA TO
THE PRESIDENT TO CONTACT THE NEW
INCOMING PRESIDENT OF MEXICO AND
JUST ASK HIM TO RESOL 6 --
RESOLVE THIS CASE AND SEND HIM
HOME.
IT HAS GONE ON TOO LONG IT'S A
RIDICULOUS CASE.
I THINK THEY KNOW IT'S A
RIDICULOUS CASE BECAUSE IT WAS
AN ACCIDENT.
IT'S A CASE THAT THEIR OWN
MILITARY SENT LES TO THE JUDGES
AND PROSECUTORS SAYING THIS GUN
IS NOT ON THE RESTRICTED LIST
THAT IT IS TRYING TO RESTRICT
ASSAULT RIFLES ESSENTIALLY.
THIS ISN'T ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
THE PROSECUTORS AND THE JUDGES
HAVE REFUSED TO CONSIDER THAT.
I AM JUST ASKING THE PRESIDENT
TO GET INVOLVED AT THIS POINT.
>> HAMMER'S NEXT HEAR SOMETHING
SCHEDULED FOR JANUARY 17TH.
MORE ON THAT ON FOX AND FRIENDS
LATER THIS MORNING.
>>> THE TIME IS NOW 20 MINUTES
AFTER THE HOUR.
TROOPS PUTTING OUR LIVES ON THE
LINE TO PROTECT US FROM THE
TALIBAN.
WHY IS THE ARMY TELLING SOLDIERS
TO BE SO NICE TO THEM?
>> GET UP STAND UP.
A STUDY SAYS STANDING AND
SITTING COULD TELL YOU HOW LONG
YOU WILL LIVE.
This Bible changed the world.
I'm Kirk Cameron. Four Hundred
years ago
our forefathers risked their
lives to bring this Bible to the
shores of America.
Because it contained
the principals for economic
liberty,
political liberty and religious
freedom. The 1599 Geneva Bible.
It was the first
complete english
translation, complete with
chapters,
numbered verses and 300,000
utterly unique study notes.
It actually came out
before the King James
Version and because the
government didn't authorize it,
it was outlawed. But it was a
Bible by the people,
for the people, the book
that built America.
And now for the first time
in 400 years it's
available again in a beautiful
leather edition. I have one,
I want you to have yours too.ev
and get your copy
of this rare and historic
version of God's Word today.
Thank you and may God bless you.
>> WELCOME BACK.
IT IS 22 AFTER THE TOP OF THE
HOUR.
HERE'S QUICK HEADLINES FOR YOU.
THREE NEW YORK CITY POLICE
OFFICERS WHO RESPONDED DURING
THE SEPTEMBER 11TH TERROR
ATTACKS WILL GET ENHANCED
BENEFITS AFTER THEY WERE
ORIGINALLY DECLINED TO THEM.
THE TOP COURTS RULED IN THEIR
FAVOR.
STATE LAWMAKERS WANTED THE
OFFICERS TO PROVE THEIR CANCERS
SPECIFICALLY RESULTED FROM THE
RESCUE AND CLEANUP AFTER 9-11.
MORE JUSTICE COMING IN THE
MADOFF PONZI SCHEME.
BERNIE MADOFF'S BROTHER PETER
DESERVES TO SPEND THE NEXT
TEN-YEARS IN PRISON FOR HIS ROLE
IN THE 2$20 BILLION FRAUD CASE.
HE WILL BE SENTENCED NEXT WEEK.
>>> IT IS NOW TIME FOR YOUR FOX
HEALTH FIX.
ANNA KOOIMAN IS HERE FOR THE
ROUNDUP OF THE TOP MEDICAL
STORIES.
WHAT YOU HAVE TOFOR US?
>> EVERYBODY KNOWS SMOKING IS
BAD FOR YOU, RIGHT?
EVEN LIGHT SMOKING CAN DOUBLE
THE RISK OF SUDDEN DEATH FOR
WOMEN.
RESEARCHERS FROM THE RESEARCHES
HEALTH STUDY FOUND WOMEN WHO
SPOKE ONE CIGARETTE PER DAY HAVE
A HIRE RISK FOR DEADLY HEART
CONDITION FOR WOMEN.
HOWEVER WOMEN WHO QUIT DID
REDUCE THEIR RISK SIGNIFICANTLY.
CAN DETERMINING HOW LONG YOU
LIVE BE AS SIMPLE AS SITTING
DOWN?
A STUDY FOR JOURNAL OF
CARDIOVASCULAR SYNDROME SAID IT
COULD.
SITTING WITHOUT HELP CONSIDERS
THEIR MORALITY.
IF A PERSON CAN GET UP WITH
LITTLE OR NO HELP THEY ARE LICK
LIE TO LIVE LOPPINGER BECAUSE
THEY ARE MORE ACTIVE.
IF A TERNE STRUGGLED OR NEEDED A
HAND THEY WERE MORE LIKELY TO
DIE EARLIER.
THE STUDY LOOKED AT 2,000 MIDDLE
AGED MEN AND WOMEN OVER A 6 YEAR
PERIOD.
FINALLY YOU HEARD THE WARNINGS
ABOUT BPA BEING DANGEROUS FOR
BABIES BUT IT MAY NOW BE HARMING
YOUR PET.
>> FOE FOUND WHEN DOGS CHEWED ON
PLASTIC TOYS IT INCREASED THE
BPA.
NO WORD ON WHAT EFFECT BPA COULD
HAVE ON DOGS.
THE CHEMICALS COULD ADVERSELY
EFFECT HUMAN MOHORMONES.
VISIT FOX NEWS HEALTH.COM FOR
MORE INFORMATION ON THESE
STORIES.
>>> 25 MINUTES AFTER THE HOUR.
COMING UP TALK ABOUT REGULATION
NATION.
THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT IS NOW
ORDERING THE STATE OF VIRGINIA
TO SOMEHOW REGULATE RAIN WATER.
OKAY BUT VIRGINIA GETS ITS
CHANCE TO RAIN ON THE FED'S
PARADE LATER TODAY.
WHAT A VIEW.
IT MAY BE ONE OF THE MOST
AMAZING THINGS ALL YEAR.
A LOT OF US AROUND HERE SAW IT
LAST NIGHT.
A LOT OF YOU MISSED IT.
HE GETS A GOLD RECORD.
You know how painful heartburn
can be.
For fast, long lasting relief,
use doctor recommended
Gaviscon®.
Only Gaviscon® forms a
protective barrier that helps
block stomach acid from
splashing up-
relieving the pain quickly.
Try fast, long lasting
Gaviscon®.
relieving the pain quickly.
AVOID BAD.FATS.
DON'T GO OVER 2000...
1200 CALORIES A DAY.
CARBS ARE BAD. CARBS ARE GOOD.
THE STORY KEEPS CHANGING.
SO I'M NOT LISTENING...
TO ANYONE BUT MYSELF.
I KNOW BETTER NUTRITION
WHEN I SEE IT:
GREAT GRAINS.
GREAT GRAINS CEREAL STARTS
WHOLE AND STAYS WHOLE.
SEE THE SEAM?
MORE PROCESSED FLAKES LOOK
NOTHING LIKE NATURALRAINS.
YOU CAN'T ARGUE WITH
NUTRITION YOU CAN SEE.
GREAT GRAINS.
SEARCH GREAT GRAINS
AND SEE FOR YOURSELF.
FOR MULTI GRAIN FLAKES TT ARE
ANXCELLENT SOURCE OF FIBER
TRY GREAT GRAINS
BANANA NUT CRUNCH
AND CRANBERRY ALMOND CRUNCH.
>> WELCOME BACK TO "FOX &
FRIENDS FIRST".
I AM HEATHER CHILDERS.
>> I AM HEATHER NAUERT.
IT IS NOW HALF PAST THE HOUR.
IT IS TIME FOR THE TOP 5@5:30.
WE ARE GETTING TO LISTEN IN ON
THE CHILLING 911 CALL THAT WAS
MADE MOMENTS AFTER DALLAS COWBOY
PLAYER CRASHED HIS CAR KILLING
HIS TEAMMATES.
LISTEN TO THIS.
>> IS ANYBODY INJURED?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
IT JUST HAPPENED.
THERE'S A CAR UPSIDE DOWN AND
THERE WAS SMOKE EVERY WHERE.
>> THERE'S A CAR IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE ROAD ON FIRE UPSIDE DOWN.
>> WE HAVE IT.
WE ARE ON THE WAY, OKAY?
>> THIS IS A LOOK AT THE SCENE
OF THIS SATURDAY'S ACCIDENT.
IT WAS OBTAINED BY TMZ.
JOSH BRENT HAD A BLOOD ALCOHOL
LEVEL OVER THE LIMIT WHEN HE
KILLED HIS TEAMMATE IN THE DWI
ACCIDENT.
>> ARE TROOPS IN AFGHANISTAN TO
BLAME FOR THE RECENT STRING OF
INSIDER ATTACKS?
A NEW DRAFT OF THE ARMY CRAFT
SAYS THE CULTURE HAS LED TO
DEADLY ATTACKS BY THE AFGHAN
FORCES.
U.S. TROOPS SHOULD NOT SPEAK OUT
AGAINST THE TALIBAN OR DEFEND
WOMEN'S RIGHTS.
THE BOOK BE A'S MESS SJ IS N
NOT -- MESSAGE IS NOT SITTING
WELL WITH THE GENERAL.
63 PEOPLE DIED IN INSIDER
ATTACKS THIS YEAR ALONE.
>> THE EPA IS NOW TRYING TO
REGULATE RAIN WATER.
THAT IS EXACTLY WHAT IT IS
PROPOSING IN VIRGINIA.
A FEDERAL JUDGE WILL HEAR
ARGUMENTS FROM STATE LAWMAKERS
WHO FILE A LAWSUIT SAYING THE
PLAN IS ILLEGAL.
THE AGENCY WANTS TO CLASSIFY
WATER AS A POLLUTANT AND DOING
SO WOULD REGULATE A SINGLE CREEK
THAT COULD COST THE STATE A
BILLION DOLLARS AND FORCE PEOPLE
OUT OF THEIR HOMES.
>>> WHAT THEY ARE GOING TO HAVE
TO DO IS THINGS LIKE TAKE
PEOPLE'S HOUSES, EVICT THEM,
KNOCK THE HOUSES DOWN AND PLANT
GRASS SO THE WATER DOESN'T FLOW.
>> LISTEN TO THIS ONE.
THE EPA SAYS WHEN THERE'S TOO
MUCH WATER IT CAN BE CLASSIFIED
AS POLLUTANT THAT GIVES THEM
REGULATORY POWER UNDER THE CLEAN
WATER ACT.
>> THE SHOW WON'T BE GOING ON AT
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
MASSACHUSETTS.
THE TRADITIONAL MOL DAY CONCERT
AT JORDAN JOHNSON ELEMENTARY HAS
BEEN CANCELED AFTER PARENTS
COMPLAINED THAT LAST YEAR'S
PERFORMANCE WAS TOO RELIGIOUS.
A SPEECH ON ANTI BULLYING WILL
TAKE THE PLACE OF THE CONCERT IN
JANUARY.
>>> WERE YOU ABLE TO SEE THIS
MORNING'S METEOR SHOWER?
HERE'S A SHOT AT IT AS STREAKS
ABOVE THE JUDEAN DESERT.
IT IS CALLED THE GEMINID SHOWER.
IT TOOK PLACE A SHORT TIME AGO.
AS MANY AS 50 STREAKS PER HOUR
WERE SEEN ALL ACROSS THE GLOBE.
HERE'S ANOTHER LOOK AT TYLER,
TEXAS.
NASA SAYS THIS YEAR'S SHOW COULD
BE THE BEST AS THE MOON'S GLARE
WON'T INTERFERE WITH THE
VISIBLE.
THAT IS YOUR TOP 5@5:00.
>>> WHILE THE PRESIDENT PROMISED
AMERICAN PEOPLE BALANCED
APPROACH HIS PROPOSALS HAVE BEEN
ANYTHING BUT.
HE WANTS FAR MORE IN TAX HIKES
THAN SPENDING CUTS.
>> THAT WAS HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER YESTERDAY TALKING ABOUT
THE STRUGGLES OF COMING TO A
FISCAL CLIFF AGREEMENT.
THA
THAT WAS HOURS BEFORE HE MET
WITH PRESIDENT OBAMA AT THE
WHITE HOUSE.
DID ANYTHING CHANGE?
DOUG LUZADER IS LIVE WITH THE
LATEST HOPEFULLY AN ANSWER.
>> THE SHORT ANSWER IS NO
AGREEMENT YET.
BUT WE MAY SEE MORE OF A
BAND-AID APPROACH AS OPPOSED TO
A BIG FIX, ALTHOUGH THAT WOULD
REQUIRE THE REPUBLICANS GIVE IN
TO THE PRESIDENT TO RAISE TAXES.
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER DID
GO TO THE WHITE HOUSE LATE
YESTERDAY TO MEET WITH THE
PRESIDENT.
NO AGREEMENT CAME OUT OF THAT
MEETING, BUT HE SAID EARLIER IN
THE DAY THAT HE WILL NOT BUDGE
ON THE PRESIDENT'S DEMAND FOR
ALMOST UNLIMITED POWER TO RAISE
THE NATION'S DEBT CEILING AS
PART OF THE DEAL.
IF PUSH HAD ASKED THE PRESIDENT
TO DO THAT IT WOULD HAVE BEEN
SHOT DOWN.
>> DO YOU THINK THERE IS ANY
CHANCE THAT SENATOR OBAMA WOULD
HAVE DONE THAT?
ZERO.
CONGRESS IS NEVER GOING TO GIVE
UP OUR ABILITY TO CONTROL THE
PURSE.
AND THE FACT IS --
>> THE PRESIDENT MEANTIME
ARRANGED INTERVIEWS WITH A
NUMBER OF LOCAL TV STATIONS TO
SLAM REPUBLICANS FOR NOT
AGREEING TO HIGHER TAXES.
>> THE BIG PROBLEM RIGHT NOW IS
REPUBLICANS AND THE HOUSE ARE
RESISTANT TO THE IDEA OF THE
WEALTHIEST AMERICANS PAYING
HIGHER TAX RATES.
I UNDERSTAND THE PHILOSOPHICAL
OBJECTION, ON THE OTHER HAND, WE
ARE WILLING TO MAKE SOME REALLY
TOUGH DECISIONS ABOUT SPENDING
CUTS.
>> ARE THEY, THOUGH?
IT IS POSSIBLE REPUBLICANS MAY
GIVE IN ON LETTING THOSE TOP TAX
RATES FIRE AND REVERT BACK TO
CLINTON LEVELS.
IT WOULD PUSH BIG ARGUMENT OVER
THE DEBT CEILING AND SPENDING
CUTS THE NEXT YEAR.
>>> DOUG LUZADER IN WASHINGTON
FOR US.
THANKS SO MUCH, DOUG.
>> BEFORE YOU LEAVE THE HOUSE
LET'S GET THE FIST DEGREE
WEATHER UPDATE WITH JANICE DEAN.
YOU ARE FOLLOWING THE STORM OUT
WEST I AM HAPPY ABOUT THIS.
WE ARE GOING SKIING.
>> YOU ARE GOING SKIING WHERE?
>> MONTANA.
>> AND THERE WILL BE LOTS OF
SNOW.
>> A LOT OF FOLKS WILL BE HAPPY
BECAUSE WE HAVE A STORM SYSTEM
THAT WILL BRING A LOT OF SNOW
ACROSS THE WEST.
WE HAVE TO PAY ATTENTION TO THIS
BECAUSE THIS STORM IS ALSO GOING
TO EFFECT THE CENTRAL U.S. AND
EVEN THE EAST COAST.
SO WHAT ARE WE TALKING ABOUT
HERE?
RAIN AND SNOW FOR THE SOUTHWEST.
ALSO SYSTEM ACROSS THE
NORTHWEST.
IN THE NEXT 24-HOURS BLIZZARD
WARNINGS.
10-18 INCHES OF SNOW IN SOME
CASES TWO FEET.
GUSTS 40 MILES PER HOUR.
WE HAVE A BLIZZARD WARNING
PORTIONS OF SOUTHERN NEW MEXICO.
THIS STORM IS ON THE MOVE.
BY SATURDAY ACROSS THE CENTRAL
U.S. AND SUNDAY PART OF THIS
ENERGY WORKING ITS WAY ACROSS
THE SOUTHEAST AND EVEN A LITTLE
BIT OF SNOW ACROSS THE
NORTHEAST.
ACROSS THE BIG CITY LOOKING GOOD
ESPECIALLY PORTLAND WITH THE
SYSTEM MOVING IN.
HAVE YOURSELF A GREAT WEEKEND.
HEATHER BACK TO YOU.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> TALK TO YOU LATER.
>> LA REED ANNOUNCED HE WILL
SOON BE AN X JUDGE ON THE X
FACTOR.
HE WILL GO FWOOK HIS JOB AS
CHAIRMAN OF EPIC RECORDS.
THE PAIR ARE ACCUSED OF FALSELY
LABELLING A MAN AS A GRAND THEFT
AUTO SUSPECT ON THEIR NEW SPIKE
REALITY SHOW CALLED BIG EASY
JUSTICE WHICH FIX A BOUNTY
HUNTER ON UNSUSPECTS CRIMINALS.
THEY ARE PUTTING THE FUN BACK IN
FUNERALS.
IT ORDERED THE PILOTS FOR BEST
EV
FUNERAL EVER.
A FUNERAL PARLOR WHO HAS A
DIFFERENT APPROACH TO FINAL
ARRANGEMENTS.
>> NOW IT IS TIME FOR YOUR
STARTING LINEUP.
YOUR TOP SPORTS STORIES.
WE START WITH THURSDAY NIGHT
FOOTBALL AND A HUGE GAME FOR THE
CINCINNATI BENGALS.
TURNOVERS WAS THE KEY TO THIS
ONE THEY GAVE THE BALL AWAY FIVE
TIMES.
WHAT HAS BEEN A MESSY SEASON FOR
THEM.
THEY WIN BIG 34-13.
A BIG MOVE TO TELL YOU ABOUT IN
BASEBALL.
FREE AGENT JOSH HAMILTON AGREES
TO A DEAL WITH LOS ANGELES.
THE DEAL IS WORTH 125 MMM
DOLLARS OVER 5 YEARS.
>>> A BIG BLOW TO THE NCAA BIG
EAST.
SEVEN OF THE CONFERENCE
BASKETBALL ONLY SCHOOLS HAVE
DECIDED TO JOIN THEIR OWN
LEAGUE.
THE PARTING SCHOOLS ARE PATH
CATHOLIC SCHOOLS GEORGETOWN,
MARQUETTE, SETON HALL AND
VILLANUEVA.
IT IS 20 MINUTES BEFORE THE
HOUR.
COMING UP TODAY IT IS THE LAST
DAY STATES CAN JOIN THE OBAMA
CARE HEALTHCARE EXCHANGES.
WITH ONLY A HANDFUL OF STATES
SIGNING UP WILL THE PRESIDENT'S
PLANS WORK?
WE WILL TALK ABOUT THAT.
>> TALK ABOUT A MESSAGE FROM GOD
SOME LEARNED THE HARD WAY ABOUT
THE TEN COMMANDMENTS.
THOU SHALL NOT STEAL.
New Trident Layers
Juicy Berry + Tangy Tangerine
is a thrilling, dual-flavored
ride to mouth fun-town.
But it's not like
everyone is going to
break into
a karaoke jam session.
♪
This will literally
probably never happen.
I HEARD YOU GUYS CAN SHIP GROUND
FOR LESS THAN THE UPS STORE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I'VE LEARNED THE ONLY WAY TO GET
A HOLIDAY DEAL IS TO CAMP OUT.
YOU KNOW WE'VE BEEN OPEN
ALL NIGHT.
IS THIS A TRICK
TO GET MY SPOT?
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SAVE ON GROUND SHIPPING
AT FEDEX OFFICE.
[ engine revs ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THE MERCEDES-BENZ WINTER EVENT
IS BACK,
WITH THE PERFECT VEHICLE
THAT'S JUST RIGHT FOR YOU,
NO MATTER WHICH LIST YOU'RE ON.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
C250 FOR $349 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
A OO HUNDREDS OF PRIVATE
SECURITY WORKERS THREATENING TO
WALK OFF THE JOBS DAYS BEFORE
CHRISTMAS IF THEIR DEMANDS
AREN'T MET.
LYDIA?
>>> GOOD MORNING HEATHER.
THAT'S EXACTLY RIGHT.
FIVE DAYS BEFORE CHRISTMAS.
THAT'S WHEN THESE WORKERS ARE
THREATENING TO STRIKE 300 OF
THOSE SECURITY GUARDS THEY ARE
NONUNIONIZED WORKERS THREATENING
TO STRIKE, WALK OFF THE JOB
RIGHT HERE AT JFK AIRPORT.
THEY HAVE AN IMPORTANT JOB.
WHAT THE SECURITY GUARDS DO IS
THEY DIRECT TRAFFIC IN FRONT OF
THE TERMINAL.
THEY GUARD ALARM DOORS.
THEY HAVE A PROTEST HERE AT J
JFC -- JFK CLAIMING HTHEY ARE
UNDER PAID AND DON'T HAVE THE
PROPER EQUIPMENT.
HERE'S WHAT ONE OF THE WORKERS
HAD TO SAY.
>> THEY REFUSE TO GIVE US PROPER
EQUIPMENT WORKING EQUIPMENT,
RADIOS.
THEY REFUSE TO GIVE US PROPER
TRAINING.
>> THESE ARE NONUNIONIZED
WORKERS BUT THEY ARE BACKED BY
ONE OF THE LARGEST UNIONS IN THE
COUNTRY.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT THIS ACTUALLY
MEANS FOR TRAVELERS.
BUT TRAVELERS WE SPOKE TO ARE
DEFINITELY WORRIED.
FOR NOW THAT'S THE LATEST HERE
AT JFK AIRPORT.
>> THEY HAVE DECIDED WHETHER OR
NOT THEY ARE JOINING THE
HEALTHCARE EXCHANGES.
SO FAR MORE STATES ARE OPTING
OUT THAN SIGNING UP FOR IT.
HERE'S THE QUESTION, WILL THE
PRESIDENT'S PLAN WORK?
DIANE MACEDO MAY HAVE THE
ANSWER.
>> CAN'T TELL YOU THAT BUT I CAN
BREAKDOWN HOW THE STATES ARE
DIVVYING THIS UP.
THE DEADLINE IS HERE.
THEY HAVE TO DECIDE IF THEY ARE
GOING TO SET UP THEIR OWN
MARKETPLACE FOR PRIVATE HEALTH
INSURANCE OR IF THEY ARE GOING
TO LEAVE IT TO THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT.
TELL ME IF YOU NOTICE ANY
TRENDS.
20 STATES HAVE GONE FOR THE
LATER OPTION OUTRIGHT.
THEY ARE NOT CREATING THEIR OWN
EXCHANGES.
MONTANA REPUBLICAN STATE
LEGISLATURE REQUESTED TO SET UP
AN EXCHANGE THERE.
THEY WILL HAVE A FEDERAL
EXCHANGE THERE AS WELL.
INDIANA GOVERNOR DEFERRED THE
DECISION TO GOVERNOR ELECT.
HE DOESN'T PLAN ONSETING UP THE
STATE EXCHANGE.
THAT LOOKS LIKE ANOTHER NO.
MISSOURI VOTED TO BAN GOVERNOR
JAY NIXON FROM CREATING A BEAS
IKS CHANGE WITHOUT THE VOTE OR
APPROVAL OF THE STATE
LEGISLATURE.
THAT'S ANOTHER ONE FOR THE
FEDERAL EXCHANGE.
UTAH HAS AN EXCHANGE BUT THEY
ARE WAITING TO SEE IF IT MEETS
FEDERAL APPROVAL.
19 PERCENT SAY THEY WILL HAVE
THEIR STATE EXCHANGES.
ARKANSAS, DELAWARE, MICHIGAN,
NORTH CAROLINA AND WEST VIRGINIA
HAVE PARTNERSHIP EXCHANGES WITH
THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT AND
VIRGINIA AND FLORIDA ARE
UNDECIDED.
FIVE GOVERNORS BROKE PARTY LINES
HERE.
BILL BRYANT OF MISSISSIPPI.
BUSH OF IDAHO, MARTINEZ OF NEW
MEXICO AND BRIAN SAND VOLUME OF
NEVADA.
EVERYONE ELSE CHOOSE AS EXPE
EXPECTED.
REPUBLICANS OPTED OUT DEMOCRATS
SUPPORT.
>>> 50 MINUTES BEFO-- 15 MINUTE
BEFORE THE TOP OF THE HOUR.
THE RANKING OF THE RUDEST
AIRLINES AND RUDEST EMPLOYEES
COMING UP NEXT.
>>> PAY TANKS TO THIS.
IF YOU HAVEN'T CHECKED THE WIFE
OR GIRLFRIEND OFF YOUR HOLIDAY
SHOPPING LIST WE HAVE HELP FOR
YOU.
WHAT WOMEN REALLY WANT THIS
CHRISTMAS.
>> FIRST LET'S CHECK IN WITH
BRIAN KILL LEMEADE TO SEE WHAT'
COMING UP ON FOX AND FRIENDS.
WHAT DO YOU HAVE?
>> WE ARE GOING TO TALK ABOUT
SUSAN RICE WHY SHE DECIDED NOT
TO BE SECRETARY OF STATE WHAT
WILL SHE ACTUALLY BE.
WHY SO MANY PEOPLE ARE RUNNING
TO THE HEALTH CLUB SO HE CAN SIT
THERE IN THEIR OUTFITS.
SURE TO GET UNDER YOUR SKIN
ABOUT SOMETHING YOU WOULDN'T
EXPECT.
AND WE ARE GOING TO BE TALKING
ABOUT CHUCK CABLE BECOMING THE
NEXT SECRETARY OF DEFENSE ALL
COMING UP ON "FOX & FRIENDS" FOR
THREE HOURS ON THIS WONDERFUL
FRIDAY AND REEXAMINE THIS DAY.
IS IT AS NICE AS I THINK IT IS?
WE WILL THINK ABOUT THAT.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
THIS IS ANOTHER!
TA-DAA!
TRY CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG.
IT CLEANS SO WELL AND YOU CAN
USE UP TO FOUR TIMES LESS
THAN THE LEADING VALUE
BRAND.
OH! THERE IT IS.
THANKS SON.
HEY!
[ Female Announcer ]
CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG
HAS A DURACLEAN TEXTURE
THAT CAN HELP YOU GET CLEAN
WHILE STILL USING LESS.
AND IT'S FOUR TIMES STRONGER
VERSUS THE LEADING VALUE BRAND.
CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG HELPS KEEP
YOU AND YOUR UNDERWEAR CLEAN.
WE ALL GO. WHY NOT ENJOY THE GO
WITH CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG?
>> YOU WANT A FRIENDLY FLIGHT?
YOU MIGHT NOT WANT TO FLY WITH
AMERICAN AIRLINES.
ACCORDING TO A SURVEY BY
TRAVELERS THEY HAVE THE RUDEST
EMPLOYEES.
UNITED AIRLINES TOOK SECOND
PLACE WITH THE UNFLATTERING
LABEL.
SCORING BEST IT'S A TIE BETWEEN
ALASKA, JETBLUE AND VIRGIN
AMERICA.
TWO THIEVES LEARNING A PAINFUL
LESSON WHILE TRYING TO ROB A
CHURCH.
THEY GRABBED THE ELECTRICAL
CABLE FOR THE EXPLOSION THE
CHURCH IS WITHOUT POWER AND THE
CHURCH IS LOOKING FOR THE GUYS
RESPONSIBLE.
>> I WANT THIS GIFT.
>> SOMETHING FUN.
IT IS TIME FOR THE HOLIDAY WISH
LIST OUR WEEKLY SEGMENT GIVING
YOU GREAT GIFT IDEAS.
THIS WEEK IT'S ALL ABOUT THE
LADIES.
A NEW STUDY SAYS THAT MEN
APPARENTLY ARE FEELING EXTRA
GENEROUS THIS YEAR AND THEY ARE
GOING TO EVEN SPEND MORE MONEY
THAN WOMEN ON GIFTS SO THAT IS
GOOD NEWS.
WITH HOT GIFT IDEAS IS THE
CREATOR OF YOUNG MERRY CHIC.COM.
>> THAT'S THE BEST NEWS I HAVE
HEARD ALL DAY ALL WEEK.
>> WE HAVE IDEAS FOR THEM THAT
ARE AFFORDABLE AND THAT THEY
WOULD LIKE.
>> EVERYONE LOVES THIS.
IT IS RIGHT AROUND $40.
YOU GET A LOT OF ITEMS IN ONE.
YOU GET THE BODY LOTION LIKE A
POLISH.
I THINK IT'S A GREAT GO TO GIFT
AND SOMETHING YOU CAN KEEP IN
CASE YOU NEED AN EXTRA GIFT THIS
YEAR.
>> IF YOU CAN'T MAKE A DECISION
THIS HAS A LITTLE BIT OF
EVERYTHING.
>> ONE OF MY FAVORITE ITEMS IS
LAURA MERCIER CAN'T EVER HAVE
ENOUGH LIP GLOSS.
I AM ALWAYS LOSING IT.
LAURA MERCIER HAS MANY LIP
GLOSSES IN LOTS OF COLORS.
THAT'S A GOOD ONE.
THEY HAVE THESE GREAT MAKEUP
PALLETS.
THIS IS PERFECT IF YOU HAVE
SOMEBODY GOING TO A LOT OF
HOLIDAY PARTIES.
IT'S A GREAT SIZE YOU CAN FIT
RIGHT IN YOUR CLUTCH.
>> SO JEWELRY.
>> WE ALWAYS LIKE JEWELRY.
>> CHARMING CHARLIE HAS THESE
GREAT AFFORDABLE STACKABLE
BENGAL BRACELETS AND PRETTY
EARRINGS AS WELL.
THEY ARE A SUPER AFFORDABLE
LINE.
IT'S 14-19 DOLLARSES.
IT'S A GREAT OPTION.
YOU CAN PICK UP A FEW OF THESE
MAYBE INSTEAD OF JUST GRABBING
ONE.
>> THESE ARE WILL 1997 AND 14.97
IN PRETTY JEWEL TONES AS WELL.
>> YOU AND I HAVE ON THESE GREAT
MONOGRAM NECKLACES FROM C
WONDER.
I THINK SOMETHING WITH AN
INITIAL ON IT IS SO MUCH MORE
PERSONAL.
YOU TOOK A MINUTE TO PICK OUT
SOMETHING REALLY THOUGHTFUL.
>> I LOVE THESE.
THIS I MIGHT DO MYSELF.
>> MOVING ON TO THE TECH GIFT.
>> THIS IS ONE OF MY FAVORITE
ITEMS.
EVERYONE MAKES FUN OF ME BECAUSE
THEY THINK I HAVE THIS BIG PHONE
CASE IT'S ACTUALLY A CHARGER.
IT EXTENDS THE BATTERY LIFE OF
YOUR iPHONE FOR UP TO 11 HOURS.
I NEVER RUN OUT OF POWER.
>> WE ARE GOOD TO GO.
>> FOR $10 YOU CAN ACTUALLY GET
A MAGNETIC CASE FOR YOUR iPAD
THAT TURNS IT ON AND OFF.
THIS ACTUALLY NOT ONLY IS IT
CUTE IT'S VERY FUNCTIONAL IT
FOLDS UP AND YOU CAN PROP YOUR
iPAD ON IT.
>> I HAVE ONE OF THESE.
I LIKE THIS A LOT.
>> LAY IT ON THE INSIDE AND THEN
COACH HAS -- OF COURSE THEY HAVE
THE ICONIC BAG.
BUT IF YOU HAVE SOMEONE REALLY
FASHIONABLE TO SHOP FOR THIS IS
GREAT THIS IS AN iPAD CASE BUT
IT DOUBLES I THINK AS A CLUTCH.
YOU CAN FIT ALL KINDS OF THINGS.
BEAUTIFUL COLORS.
>> SPEAKING OF PURSES.
>> THE MAC DADDY CLUTCH.
YOU CAN BUY ONE FOR YOUR
BOYFRIEND OR GIRLFRIEND THEY
COME WITH THE GREAT COLORS IT'S
A CROSS BODY BAG NOT TOO BIG.
>> THAT'S $195.
>> AND THE BOOTS ARE BEAUTIFUL.
>> WE HAVE BEEN STARING AT
THESE.
STEVE MADDEN IS MY GO TO BRAND
FOR AFFORDABLE SHOES.
PENELOPE BOOTIE $195.
IT'S PRETTY A NICE SWAI WITH A
LOW HEEL.
>> LITTLE ON THE HIGH END.
>> THE HIG END 595 ALLISON
OLIVIA.
THEY ARE A BEAUTIFUL CLASSIC, I
KNOW THEY ARE MORE EXPENSIVE BUT
IT'S A STATEMENT PIECE.
IF YOU WANT TO GET SOMETHING
WITH A WOW FACTOR.
>> THOSE WOULD GO WELL WITH THIS
COAT.
>> THIS COAT FROM BCBG IS A
GREAT COAT.
SPARKLY.
PERFECT FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
BEAUTIFUL.
ALSO CLASSIC.
>> NEUTRAL SO YOU CAN DRESS IT
DOWN OR DRESS IT UP FOR THE
HOLIDAYS.
>> AND KEEP IT FOR YEARS.
>> THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
APPRECIATE IT.
ALL OF THE MEN AT HOME HOPE YOU
TOOK SOME NOTES.
>>> DON'T FORGET TO TUNE IN NEXT
FRIDAY WHEN CHRIS WILL JOIN US
AGAIN AND GIVE US SOME GIFT
IDEAS FOR LAST MINUTE GIFTS AND
STOCKING STUFFERS.
VISIT US ON FOX FRIENDS
FIRST.COM FOR ALL OF THOSE
DETAILS.
NICE LIST.
AND THE TIME NOW IS 54 AFTER THE
TOP OF THE HOUR.
STILL AHEAD A WOMAN COMES HOME
TO DISCOVER HER DRIVEWAY, HER
DRIVEWAY HAS BEEN STOLEN.
WE ARE NOT MAKING THIS UP.
IT'S YOUR LAST CHANCE TO ANSWER
THE QUESTION OF THE DAY.
WE TOLD YOU THIS HOLIDAY TRAVEL
SEASON IS GOING TO BE THE
BUSIEST IN 6 YEARS.
WE WANTED TO KNOW IF YOU ARE
TRAVELING FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
IF SO, WHERE?
WE ARE READING YOUR TWEETS AND
E-MAILS NEXT.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THEY ARE A GLOWING EXAMPLE
OF WHAT IT MEANS TO BE
THE BEST.
AND AT THIS SPECIAL TIME
OF YEAR,
THEY SHINE EVEN BRIGHTER.
COME TO THE WINTER EVENT
AND GET THE MERCEDES-BENZ
YOU'VE ALWAYS WISHED FOR,
NOW FOR AN EXCEPTIONAL PRICE.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
GLK350 FOR $399 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
IF APPROXIMATE >> COUPLE OF
MINUTES BEFORE THE HOUR AS WE AD
THE UGLY.
LET CO-WORKERS HAVE BOUGHT
TICKETS AND WON A $50 MILLION
POWERBALL .
A FLORIDA WOMAN CAME HOME TO
FIND THIEVES MADE OFF WITH A
BRICK WALK WAY .
AND THE UGLY, THE FIRST
SECTION OF UKRAINE'S
GOVERNMENT.
MASSAVE BRAWL WHEN LAWMAKERS
FOUGHT OVER THE VOTE FOR THE
NEW PRIME MINISTER AND
SPEAKER.
>> EARLIER ON IN THE SHOW
TRIPLE A IS EXPECTING BUSIEST
TRAVEL DAY IN SIX YEARS.
GOOD FOR THEM .
HERE IS YOUR RESPONSES.
CHAD SAID WE LANDED IN NEW
YORK FROM SOUTH AFRICA AND
LIVE ON A SUNDAY MORNING
CRUISE NO TO THE BAHAMAS.
>> I AM HEADED TO CHINA FOR
GOLF, DINING AND FUN.
>> I AM TAKINGLET FAMILY TO
ALABAMA FOR UNCET SCITERS FOR
THE HOLIDAY.
IT IS TIME FOR THE AWESOMELY
BAD CHRISTMAS CARDS AND
PHOTOS