OBSERVER.
IT IS SEEN TO BE
CONTROVERSYAL.
SHE HAS SOME DUTIES RELATED
TO GOVERNMENT BUT MUST
REMAIN NEUTRAL ON POLITICAL
MATTERS.
DAVID CAMERON AND OTHER
PRIME MINISTERS VALUE THE
QUEEN'S ADVICE.
BILL: SHE IS WATCHING.
THOSE GUYS BETTER SHAPE UP.
SHE IS CHECKING IN MAKING
SURE THEY'RE DOING
EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT.
BY THE WAY, GREAT TO BE BACK
WITH YOU TODAY.
MARTHA: GOOD TO HAVE YOU
BACK.
YOU WERE OUT A COUPLE DAYS.
WE MISSED EACH OTHER IN THE
WHOLE CROSSOVER DEAL AND GOT
THE ALL OF FULL STORY ON
FRIDAY.
MARTHA:.
THANK YOU.
YOU DID A GREAT JOB.
IT IS HORRIFIC.
IT WILL BE WITH US FOR SOME
TIME.
BILL: WE HEARD THAT GUY
ACROSS THE STREET.
ANYWAY, LOVE YOUR FAMILY.
GIVE THEM BIG HUGS TO YOUR
FRIENDS AND HAVE A GREAT
DAY.
MARTHA: BYE, EVERYBODY, SEE
YOU TOMORROW.
"HAPPENING NOW" STARTS RIGHT
NOW.
JON: BRAND NEW STORIES AND
BREAKING NEWS.
JENNA: SCHOOLS IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, OPENING FOR THE
VERY FIRST TIME AFTER THE
DEADLY RAMPAGE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
JUST AS WE LEARN NEW DETAILS
ABOUT THE GUNMAN, TWO MORE
YOUNG VICTIMS ARE LAID TO
REST TODAY.
PLUS A MAJOR CYBERSECURITY
THREAT.
WHAT YOU NEED TO KNOW TO
PROTECT YOUR BANK ACCOUNTS
ON-LINE ESPECIALLY IN THE
NEW YEAR.
>>> A HOUR HARROWING ORDEAL
FOR A TV NEWS CORRESPONDENT
AND HIS CREW, KIDNAPPED FIVE
DAYS IN SYRIA.
THE LATEST DETAILS ON THEIR
ESCAPE.
IT'S HAUL L ALL "HAPPENING
NOW"
JENNA: GREAT TO HAVE YOU
WITH US ON THIS TUESDAY.
I'M JENNA LEE.
JON: I'M JON SCOTT.
THE LATEST ON THE TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT.
WHILE INVESTIGATORS SEARCH
FOR ANSWERS THERE ARE SOME
STUDENTS ARE HEADING BACK TO
SCHOOL RIGHT NOW.
RICK LEVENTHAL HAS THE
LATEST FROM NEWTOWN.
WHAT IS GOING ON THERE TODAY,
RICK?
>> Reporter: JON INCREDIBLY
CHALLENGING TIMES FOR THE
COMMUNITY, STRUGGLING ARE
WITH THE AFTERMATH AFTER
THAT HORRIFIC MASS MURDER.
SENDING KIDS BACK TO SCHOOL
AND REASSURING THOSE KIDS
THEY WILL BE SAFE IN THOSE
CLASSROOMS.
IN FACT SECURITY HAS BEEN
BEEFED UP AT THE SIX COOLS
IN THE NEWTOWN SCHOOL
DISTRICT THAT REOPENED THEIR
DOORS TODAY.
A SIGN IN ONE WINDOW SAID,
QUOTE, WE ARE STRONG.
THE FLAGS ARE FLYING AT
HALF-STAFF.
THE WE ALSO SAW MORE MOVING
VANS ROLLING FROM SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY WHICH IS THE ONE
SCHOOL STILL CLOSED.
IT IS STILL CONSIDERED A
CRIME SCENE.
ALL THE DESKS AND CHAIRS AND
EQUIPMENT AND SUPPLIES FROM
SANDY HOOK ARE BEING MOVED
TO ANOTHER HILL.
CHALK HILL, IN THE TOWN OF
MONROE ABOUT SEVEN MILES
AWAY.
THAT IS WHERE SCHOOL
ADMINISTRATORS HOPE THE
SURVIVORS OF SANDY HOOK CAN
GO BACK TO SCHOOL SOMETIMES
PERHAPS LATER THIS WEEK,
JON.
JON: THERE ARE POGUE TO BE
MORE FUNERALS TODAY?
>> WE HAD TWO FUNERALS
YESTERDAY.
TWO MORE FUNERALS TODAY.
A HEAVY POLICE PRESENCE
OUTSIDE THE CHURCH TODAY FOR
FUNERAL SERVICES.
THE FIRST THIS MORNING HELD
FOR 6-YEAR-OLD JAMES
MATTIOLI, AT ST. ROSE OF
LIMA CHURCH DOWN THE ROAD.
HIS FAMILY SAID JAMES LOVED
RECESS AND MATH.
HE WAS BORN FOUR WEEKS
BEFORE HIS DUE DATE.
THEY JOKED HE CAME EARLY
BECAUSE HE WAS HUNGRY.
AT NOON, SERVICES FOR
ANOTHER FIRST-GRADER,
JESSICA REKOS, ALSO AT ROSE.
SHE LOVED EVERYTHING ABOUT
HORSES, READING AND DRAWING
STORIES ABOUT THEM.
THE GOVERNOR TALKED ABOUT
HOW DIFFICULT IT IS TO FIND
WORDS THAT COMFORT THE
FAMILIES.
YOU CAN UNDERSTAND WHY.
THESE ARE LITTLE KIDS.
THEY WERE 6 AND 7 YEARS OLD.
THEY WERE JUST BEGINNING TO
EXPLORE THE WORLD AROUND
THEM, JON AND IT WAS TAKEN
AWAY FROM THEM.
JON: JUST SUCH IMMENSE
SADNESS AND GOES ON FOR DAYS
AND DAYS FOREVER, REALLY.
RICK LEVENTHAL, THANK YOU.
IN A FEW MINUTES WE'LL TALK
TO A FORMER FBI INVESTIGATOR
BILLION WHAT LAW ENFORCEMENT
IS DOING TO ANSWER THE
QUESTIONS LEFT IN THE WAKE
OF THIS TRAGEDY.
JENNA: NEW DETAILS ON A
SHOOTING AT A MOVIE THEATER
IN TEXAS THAT YOU MIGHT NOT
HAVE HEARD ABOUT OVER LAST
SEVERAL DAYS.
HEATHER NAUERT WITH THE
LATEST.
>> Reporter: A TERRIFYING
SHOOTING TAKING PLACE AT A
RESTAURANT BEFORE IT SPILLED
INTO AN ADJACENT PARKING LOT
AND INTO A MOVIE THEATER
COMPLEX JUST ACROSS THE WAY.
THIS HAPPENED SUNDAY NIGHT,
IN SAN ANTONIO, TEXAS.
THE SUSPECT, A 19-YEAR-OLD
COOK AT A RESTAURANT WHERE
THE SHOOTING STARTED IS
BEING HELD ON $10 MILLION
BOND.
HERE IS WHAT COPS BELIEVE
WHAT HAPPENED SUNDAY NIGHT.
JESUS GARCIA AND HIS
GIRLFRIEND APPARENTLY WORKED
TOGETHER AT CHINA GARDEN
RESTAURANT.
THEY APPARENTLY BROKEN UP.
GARCIA SEE YAW, SEEN RIGHT
THERE, ALLEGEDLY GRABBED HIS
GUN AND WENT LOOKING FOR A
COWORKER AT THE RESTAURANT.
WHEN HE ARRIVED HE STARTED
FIRING AT EMPLOYEES WHO RAN
FROM THE BUILDING INTO A
PARKING LOT AND FINALLY
TAKING COVER INSIDE THE
BATHROOM OF A CROWDED MOVIE
THEATER NEARBY.
NOW THE ENTIRE WAY GARCIA
ALLEGEDLY FIRING HIS GLOCK
HAND DPUN AS HE HUNTED FOR
HIS TARGET.
>> WE HEARD POPPING.
IT HAD TO BE SEMIAUTOMATIC.
WE THOUGHT WE WERE GOING TO
DIE.
>> I GOT ALL MY KIDS AGAINST
THE WALL.
HE WAS DOING LIKE THAT AND I
WAS STANDING AGAINST THE
DOOR.
>> Reporter: HOW
FRIGHTENING.
THOSE INSIDE THE THEATER
WERE SCARED THAT AN
AURORA-STYLE SHOOTING WAS
TAKES PLACE RIGHT THERE.
LUCKILY THERE WAS OFF-DUTY
SHERIFF'S DEPUTY WORKING
SECURITY AT THE THEATER THAT
NIGHT.
SHE HEARD THE SHOTS AND TOOK
DOWN THE SUSPECT STOPPING
HIS MANHUNT.
>> WE WERE FORTUNATE WE HAVE
THE OFFICER WAS WELL-TRAINED
AND TOOK THE ACTION SHE
NEEDED TO TAKE.
I BELIEVE SHE SAVED AS MANY
LIVES AS SHE HAD TO SAVE.
>> Reporter: THE SUSPECT
SHOT AT ONE MAN AND FIRED AT
A POLICE DEPARTMENT PATROL
CAR IN THE PARKING LOT.
WE DON'T KNOW HOW MANY
ROUNDS HE GOT OFF BEFORE THE
DEPUTIES STOPPED HIM.
YOU CAN IMAGINE PEOPLE IN
THE RESTAURANT, THE PARKING
LOT AND THEATER WERE
ABSOLUTELY TERRIFIED.
JENNA.
JENNA: MORE ON THAT STORY AS
WE GET IT, HEATHER.
THANK YOU.
JON: TURNING ATTENTION TO
WASHINGTON.
NEW INFORMATION BREAKING IN
THE LAST HOUR THAT A BACKUP
PLAN IS IN THE WORKS FOR
REPUBLICANS IN CASE THE
WHITE HOUSE AND CONGRESS CAN
NOT REACH A DEAL ON THE
FISCAL CLIFF BY THE END OF
THE YEAR.
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER
SPOKE ABOUT IT A MINUTES
AGO.
>> OUR PLAN B WOULD PROTECT
AMERICAN TAXPAYERS WHO MAKE
A MILLION DOLLARS OR LESS
AND HAVE ALL OF THEIR
CURRENT RATES EXTENDED.
I CONTINUE TO HAVE HOPE THAT
WE CAN REACH A BROADER
AGREEMENT WITH THE
WHITE HOUSE THAT WOULD
REDUCE SPENDING AS WELL AS
HAVE REVENUES ON THE TABLE.
JON: DESPITE THE EXISTENCE
OF THIS PLAN B NEGOTIATIONS
ARE MOVING FORWARD BETWEEN
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND SPEAKER
BOEHNER TO TRY TO AVOID THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
ED HENRY IS LIVE AT THE
WHITE HOUSE.
SO TELL US A LITTLE BIT MORE
ABOUT PLAN B.
WHAT IS IT, ED?
>> Reporter: GOOD TO
JON.
YOU KNOW THE PRESIDENT'S
POSITION ALL ALONG YOU ONLY
RAISE TAXES ON PEOPLE MAKING
OVER $250,000.
REPUBLICANS SAID LOOK, THAT
WILL END UP NOT JUST HITTING
INDIVIDUALS BUT A LOT OF
SMALL BUSINESSES.
IT WILL RESULT IN THEM NOT
CREATING JOBS, ET CETERA.
SO YOU HEAR THE SPEAKER
SAYING LOOK, LET'S HAVE A
HOUSE VOTE NEXT COUPLE DAYS
THAT WOULD PUT THE CAP AT
BASICALLY A MILLION DOLLARS
OR MORE.
THEN YOUR TAXES GO UP.
BUT PROTECT PEOPLE UNDER
THAT MILLION DOLLAR RANGE.
THAT WOULD, IF IT WERE TO
PASS, WOULD EXTEND THE BUSH
TAX RATES ESSENTIALLY FOR
ANYBODY MAKING UNDER A
MILLION DOLLARS OR LESS.
THEN YOU MOVE FORWARD, GET
THROUGH THE END OF THE YEAR.
YOU SAVE SOME SPENDING
ISSUES AND WHAT NOT UNTIL
NEXT YEAR BUT YOU SORT OF
AVOID THE FISCAL CLIFF IN
THE SHORT TERM AND ERIC
CANTOR, THE HOUSE MA
AUTHORITY -- MAJORITY LEADER
SAID THIS MAY BE THE ONLY
OPTION BECAUSE THE PRESIDENT
IS NOT PUTTING ENOUGH
SPENDING CUTS ON THE TABLE.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> THE PRESIDENT HAS NOT YET
THERE.
HE HAS NOT COME TO WHERE HE
NEEDS TO BE IN ORDER TO FOR
US TO PUSH THROUGH A BILL
THAT REALLY DOES BEGIN TO
ADDRESS THE PROBLEM AND AS
THE SPEAKER SAID THAT'S WHY
WE'RE DISCUSSING AN
ALTERNATIVE PLAN AND IF THE
PRESIDENT AND THE
WHITE HOUSE CAN NOT COME OUR
WAY.
>> Reporter: BREAKING LAST
FEW MOMENTS, HOUSE DEMOCRATS
CAME OUT AFTER CLOSED-DOOR
MEETING SAYING THEY'RE
HEARING THAT RANK-AND-FILE
HOUSE REPUBLICANS HAVE
ALREADY REJECTED BOEHNER-CANTOR
PLAN.
THEY DO NOT WANT TO DO THE
SHORT-TERM PLAN B.
SENATE MAJORITY LEADER HARRY
REID SAYS HE DOESN'T BELIEVE
PLAN B WOULD MAKE IT THROUGH
THE SENATE CHAMBER.
SO WE'RE STILL BASICALLY
STUCK, JON.
JON: THEY'RE TALKING ABOUT A
PLAN B, MAYBE WISHING FOR IT
BUT HOW MUCH OF A CHANCE IS
THERE THEY GET THE BIGGER
DEAL DONE?
>> Reporter: RIGHT.
SO-CALLED PLAN A WHICH HAS
ALWAYS BEEN ON THE TABLE.
THE PRESIDENT SAID LINE ON
RAISING TACK SHOULD BE
$250,000.
BOEHNER BELIEVES IT SHOULD
BE A MILLION DOLLARS OR
MORE.
THE PRESIDENT BEHIND THE
SCENES PRIVATELY AGREED TO
MOVE IT TO 400,000, CLOSER
TO BOEHNER'S MILLION DOLLAR
LINE.
JAY CARNEY SAYS THEY'RE
WILLING TO DO SPENDING CUTS
BUT THIS DEAL HAS TO INCLUDE
RAISING TACKS ON THE RICH.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> HE WOULD VETO ANY
LEGISLATION GOT TO HIS DEBT
THAT WOULD EXTEND TAX CUTS
FOR THE TOP 2%.
ANY DEAL THAT ATTEMPTED TO
REDUCE OUR DEFICIT BROADLY
FOR THE LONG TERM, A BIGGER
DEAL, THAT HE HAS BEEN
SEEKING HAS TO BE BALANCED.
>> Reporter: BUT NOW ALSO
STILL HAVE TO DEAL WITH THE
DEBT CEILING COMING DUE IN A
COUPLE OF MONTHS.
THE PRESIDENT WANTS TO RAISE
THAT DEBT CEILING FOR TWO
YEARS.
JOHN BOEHNER WE'RE TOLD PUT
AN EXTENSION OF ONE YEAR ON
THE TABLE.
I THINK THE VERY BOTTOM LINE
WITH PLAN A AND PLAN B, THEY
MADE BABY STEPS IN PROGRESS
MAYBE BUT THEY'RE STILL FAR
APART FROM A DEAL TO AVERT
THIS FISCAL CLIFF, JON.
MAYBE IT'S PLAN-C.
IF A AND B AREN'T GOING TO
WORK, THEY HAVE TO DO
SOMETHING IN THE SHORT TERM
HERE TO GET THROUGH THIS
CRISIS, JON.
JON: WHERE YOU'RE STANDING
ON THE WHITE HOUSE LAWN CAN
YOU SEE THE EDGE OF THE
FISCAL CLIFF IN THE
DISTANCE?
>> I SEE IT OUT THERE BEYOND
PENNSYLVANIA AVENUE.
IT DOESN'T LOOK TOO GOOD,
JON.
I THINK THE DEADLINE AND
POSSIBILITY OF SUCH A CLIFF
AND FALLING OFF OF IT I
THINK IS ONLY THING THAT
WILL EVENTUALLY BRING THESE
FOLKS TOGETHER.
THERE IS POTENTIAL FOR A
DEAL BECAUSE THEY DON'T WANT
TO SEE THE MARKETS REACT TO
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
THEY'RE SAYING THEY'RE FAR
APART MAKING BABY STEPS IN
PROGRESS.
THEY'RE HOPING THEY WILL GET
SOME SORT OF A DEAL.
JON: ED HENRY, OUR CHIEF
OPTIMIST.
JENNA: LET'S HOPE THE PLAN-C,
D, E, F, WHOLE ALPHABET.
THERE HAS TO BE A DEADLINE
SOMEWHERE.
MORE OUT OF WASHINGTON, D.C.
AS WE GET IT.
WE WANT TO TURN TO MAJOR
DEVELOPMENTS IN THE MIDDLE
EAST.
AFTER FIVE DAYS OF CAPTIVITY
INSIDE SYRIA NBC NEWS
CORRESPONDENT RICHARD ENGLE
AND HIS CREW ARE SAVE IN
TURKEY.
THIS HAS CLASHES BETWEEN
REBELS AND GROUPS LOYAL TO
THE PRESIDENT THERE,
PRESIDENT ASSAD.
REBELS ARE REPORTEDLY
LAUNCHING A NEW OFFENSIVE
NEAR THE CAPITAL OF
DAMASCUS.
LELAND VITTERT LIVE FROM THE
MIDDLE EAST BUREAU WITH MORE
FOR US NOW.
LELAND?
>> Reporter: JENNA WE'LL
START WITH RICHARD ENGEL IS
OUT OF CAPTIVITY.
HE WAS HELD BY A
PRO-GOVERNMENT MILITIA.
EVIDENTLY TAKEN AT GUNPOINT
WHAT THEY THOUGHT WAS
REBEL-HELD TERRITORY.
BLINDFOLDED.
WENT THROUGH MOCK EXECUTIONS
WHILE IN CAPTIVITY.
DURING THAT TIME THEY WERE
MOVED FROM SAFE HOUSE TO
SAFE HOUSE.
THEY WERE INSIDE NORTHERN
SYRIA.
AT ONE POINT WHO WERE
HOLDING THEM HAD HIS ENTIRE
CREW IN THE BACK OF A
MINIVAN.
THEY WERE MOVING TO ONE
LOCATION AND ANOTHER.
THAT WAS WHEN THERE WAS
REBEL CHECK POINT THEY
HAPPENED UPON.
THAT IS WHERE THE FIREFIGHT
HAPPENED THAT EVENTUALLY
FREED ENGEL.
EVERYONE GOT OUT OF THE VAN.
HE SAID THEY NEED HELP.
THE REBELS GOT THEM INSIDE
OF TURKEY INSIDE THE SAFE
ZONE.
FIVE DAYS OF CAPTIVITY.
NOT EVERY STORY INSIDE SYRIA
WITH JOURNALISTS END UP THIS
WAY.
FIVE JOURNALISTS ARE KILLED.
ONE AMERICAN MISSING INSIDE
OF SYRIA AS THE SITUATION
CONTINUES TO DETERIORATE.
THE LATEST VIDEO COMING OUT
OF SYRIA SHOWS THE MOMENTUM
MAY HAVE FLIPPED.
USED TO BE THE GOVERNMENT
HUNTING THE REBELS.
NOW IT IS THE REBELS HUNTING
THE GOVERNMENT.
THE GOVERNMENT MOVED INTO
MUCH MORE DEFENSIVE
POSITIONS AND ARE BEGINNING
TO HUNKER DOWN WHERE THE
REBELS ARE COMING OUT OF AN
INSURGENCY-BASED WARFARE,
BETTER ARMED, BETTER
EQUIPPED AND COORDINATED AND
BEING ABLE TO ATTACK A
NUMBER OF GOVERNMENT
POSITIONS.
STILL THEY HAVE NOT TAKEN
CONTROL OF ALEPPO OR
DAMASCUS, ANY KIND OF MAJOR
CITIES THOUGH IN SYRIA.
WE'RE SEEING SIGNS THAT THE
RUSSIANS ARE GETTING WORRIED
AT LEAST THAT PRESIDENT
ASSAD MAY NOT HOLD ON IN THE
SENSE THEY HAVE ALREADY SENT
A COUPLE OF WARSHIPS INTO
THE MEDITERRANEAN SEE TO
EVACUATE RUSSIAN CITIZENS.
ACTIONS SPEAKING LOUDER THAN
WORDS.
RUSSIANS SAYING ON ONE HAND
WE BELIEVE IN PRESIDENT
ASSAD.
WHEN YOU SEND SHIPS TO
POSSIBLY EVACUATE CITIZENS
SHOWS THEY MAY BELIEVE
PRESIDENT ASSAD IS ON HIS
LAST LEGS.
BACK TO YOU.
JENNA: MORE DEVELOPMENTS
FROM THE MIDDLE EAST AS WE
GET THEM.
LELAND, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
JON: WE'LL TAKE YOU BACK TO
THIS COUNTRY FOR THIS STORY.
YOU REMEMBER THE EX-COP IN
SUBURBAN CHICAGO WHO SEEMED
TO BE LOSING HIS WIVES?
HE BACK IS IN THE SPOTLIGHT.
HIS ATTORNEYS ARE GOING AT
IT TOO.
WAIT UNTIL YOU HEAR WHO THEY
ARE BLAMING FOR DREW
PETERSON'S MURDER
CONVICTION.
MORE ON THAT COMING UP.
>>> NEW WARNINGS FOR
COMPUTER USERS AND ALL THE
SENSITIVE INFORMATION YOU
HAVE ONLINE.
WELL TELL YOU ABOUT NEW
EVIDENCE TO SUGGEST HACKERS
ARE AFTER YOU AND YOUR
MONEY.
JON: SOME STORIES WE'RE
FOLLOWING CLOSELY THIS
MORNING.
MORE THAN 20 MEMBERS AFTER
NORTHERN ILLINOIS FRATERNITY
ARE FACING CRIMINAL CHARGES
AFTER A FRESHMAN STUDENT AT
UNIVERSITY WAS FOUND DEAD AT
THEIR HOUSE.
POLICE SAY THE 19-YEAR-OLD
DIED OF CARDIAC ARREST AFTER
AN ALLEGED HAZING INCIDENT
THAT INVOLVED HEAVY
DRINKING.
>>> THE ARMY PSYCHIATRIST
CHARGED IN THE DEADLY
FORT HOOD SHOOTING RAMPAGE
SET TO APPEAR IN MILITARY
COURT FOR HIS FIRST PRETRIAL
HEARING IN MORE THAN THREE
MONTHS.
CASE HAD BEEN ON HOLD SINCE
MAJOR NIDAL HASAN APPEALED
AN ORDER TO SHAVE HIS BEARD.
IF CONVICTED HE FACES THE
DEATH PENALTY.
>>> NEW DRAMA IN THE DREW
PETERSON MURDER TRIAL.
HIS ATTORNEYS ARE ACCUSING
THE HILLS FORMER LEAD
ATTORNEY OF MISHANDLING THE
RETIRED POLICE OFFICER HE IS
CASE.
HE IS CONVICTED OF DEATH OF
HIS THIRD WIFE, KATHLEEN
SAVIO.
HE REMAINS THE ONLY SUSPECT
IN THE DISAPPEARANCE OF HIS
FOURTH WIFE.
SHE VANISHED IN 2007.
JENNA: NOW TO A "FOX
BUSINESS ALERT." AN UPDATE
ON A STORY WE'VE BEEN
WATCHING HERE ON "HAPPENING
NOW." ONE OF THE NATION'S
LARGEST CYBERSECURITY FIRMS
WARNING RUSSIAN HACKERS MAY
BE ABOUT TO LAUNCH A MAJOR
ASSAULT ON YOUR BANK
ACCOUNT.
THE PLOT IS DUBBED, PROJECT
BLITZKRIEG.
THERE IS EVIDENCE THAT THEY
WILL TRY TO STEAL MONEY FROM
BANKS AND CREDIT UNIONS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
ADAM SHAPIRO FROM THE FOX
BUSINESS NETWORK WITH ALL OF
THIS.
QUITE A STORY ADAM.
WHO IS BEING TARGETED HERE
AND ARE WE ALL AT RISK?
>> ACCORDING TO McAFEE LABS
THEY'RE TAKING THIS AS A
CREDIBLE THREAT.
PART OF RUSSIAN HACKERS PART
OF A CRIMINAL UNDERGROUND
AND TARGETING HIGH NET WORTH
INDIVDUALS.
THEY HAVE ALREADY ACCORDING
TO McAFEE KIND OF RUN THE
TROJAN THAT IS GETTING INTO
THE COMPUTER AND ALLOWS THEM
TO GET INTO YOUR BANK
ACCOUNT.
THEY HAVE DONE THIS TO 300
TO 500 PEOPLE SINCE ABOUT
2007.
THE CYBER HACKERS ARE
CLAIMING TO HAVE TRANSFERRED
ABOUT $5 MILLION AS THEY DO
THIS.
ESSENTIALLY IT IS HIGH NET
WORTH INDIVDUALS AT ROUGHLY
30 INSTITUTIONS IN THE
UNITED STATES.
THE INSTITUTIONS ARE NOT
NAMED BUT THEY'RE GOING
AFTER NATIONAL BANKS,
INVESTMENT BANKS.
SO YOU HAVE TO PROTECT
YOURSELF BUT THEY TAKE THIS
AS A CREDIBLE THREAT.
JENNA: A CREDIBLE THREAT.
WE KNOW ABOUT IT, WE'RE TALK
ABOUT IT ON THE NEWS.
ARE THE BANKS PREPARED FOR
THIS?
>> Reporter: THAT'S A GREAT
QUESTION.
FIRST OF ALL THE ATTACK WAS
SUPPOSED TO COME SOMETIME
THIS SPRING.
IT WAS SUPPOSED TO HAPPEN
THIS FALL.
McAFEE BELIEVES IT WILL
HAPPEN THIS SPRING.
HE SPOKE WITH FREDERICK
LAYTON, THEY ARE A STRATEGIC
RISK CONSULTANCY
ORGANIZATION.
THEY SPECIALIZE IN CYBER
INTELLIGENCE ISSUES.
HE TELLS ME, THIS IS DIRECT
QUOTE, THAT THE BANKS ARE
NOT COMPLETELY READY FOR
THIS ATTACK.
McAFEE'S REPORT IS A
THOROUGH EXAMINATION AND THE
BANKS ARE GETTING READY FOR
THIS EVENT THE BEST THING
YOU CAN DO IF YOU HAVE ANY
CONCERN ABOUT THIS, CHECK
YOUR ACCOUNTS DAILY.
YOU CAN REPORT ANY BIZARRE
ACTIVITY TO THE BANK BUT YOU
HAVE TO CHECK YOUR ACCOUNT
DALELY.
THAT COMES FROM AN EXPERT.
JENNA: VERY INTERESTING.
WE HAD A CYBERSECURITY
EXPERT ON OUR SHOW LAST WEEK
THAT SAID IF YOU WANT TO USE
APPS, APPS ON THE iPHONE FOR
EXAMPLE, THOSE CAN BE MORE
SAFE THAN GOING ONLINE.
>> WRONG.
JENNA: REALLY?
THAT'S WHAT HE TOLD US.
THIS ADVICE FROM THE CIA.
>> I ASKED FREDERICK LATE
TON.
I'M NOT A CYBER EXPERT.
LAYTON SPENT MORE THAN TWO
DECADES IN MILITARY
INTELLIGENCE, PART OF THE
NSA.
HE SAID THERE IS BELIEF THAT
YOU HAVE APPLE DEVICES
YOU'RE MORE PROTECTED THEN
IF YOU'RE USING IBM BASED
DEVICE, SUCH AS A PC.
HE SAYS THAT IS NOT
ACCURATE.
JENNA: THEY HAVE A
DIFFERENCE OF OPINION.
>> Reporter: THE EXPERTS DO.
JENNA: GOOD TO CHECK YOUR
ACCOUNT.
THANK YOU, ADAM.
JON: MY SOLUTION?
I HAVE TWO KIDS IN COLLEGE
AND DON'T HAVE ANY MONEY IN
THE BANK ACCOUNT.
JENNA: THAT IS HOW IT WORKS.
JON: I AM NOT A TARGET OF
HACKERS.
JENNA: JON SCOTT, DON'T
TARGET HIM.
EMPTY POCKETS.
JON: DREAM WEATHER IS MOVING
INTO PARTS OF THE U.S. WHAT
IT COULD MEAN FOR HOLIDAY
TRAVEL AS MILLIONS GET READY
FOR CHRISTMAS.
>>> THE LATEST ON THE
INVESTIGATION IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WE'LL TALK WITH A FORMER FBI
INVESTIGATOR ABOUT WHAT LAW
ENFORCEMENT IS DOING TO
ADDRESS THE MANY
STILL-UNANSWERED QUESTIONS
CAN.
JENNA: WELCOME BACK,
EVERYONE.
EXTREME WEATHER MOVING
THROUGH PARTS OF THE COUNTRY
TODAY.
YOU HAVE HIGH WINDS AND
MOUNTAIN SNOW HITTING
PORTLAND, OREGON.
THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE SEEING ON
YOUR SCREEN.
ALSO COLORADO, UTAH, WYOMING
BRACING FOR SEVERAL FEET OF
SNOW.
METEOROLOGIST MARIA MOLINA
FROM THE FOX NEWS WEATHER
CENTER.
>> JENNA, GOOD TO SEE YOU.
NOT JUST OUT WEST BUT WE
EXPECT THE SAME SNOWSTORM TO
TRACK EASTWARD AND PRODUCE
SNOW ACROSS PARTS OF CENTRAL
PLAINS, UPPER GREAT LAKES
AND EVENTUALLY RAINFALL
ACROSS THE EAST COAST.
WE HAVE A COUPLE OF DAYS
WE'LL TRACK THE STORM SYSTEM
TO PRODUCE ALL KINDS OF
TRAVEL HEADACHES FOR ANYONE
DOING TRAVELING COMING UP
WITH CHRISTMAS ALREADY
AROUND THE CORNER.
SOME OF YOU WILL SEE A WHITE
CHRISTMAS THANKS TO THE
SNOWSTORM TRACKING EAST.
WE HAVE SNOWLINGERING ACROSS
PARTS OF WESTERN WASHINGTON,
OREGON.
EVENTUALLY THE STORM WILL
MOVE INTO THE PORTIONS OF
THE ROCKIES, DUMPING SNOW IN
THE HIGHER ELEVATION.
GOOD NEWS FOR ANYONE WANTING
TO DO SKING NEXT COUPLE DAYS
ACROSS COLORADO, EVEN UTAH.
LOOK AT PARTS OF NEBRASKA,
IOWA, WISCONSIN.
SIGNIFICANT SNOWFALL
ACCUMULATION OUT HERE IN THE
AREA SHADED IN BLUE.
THAT IS POSSIBLY OVER SIX
INCHES OF SNOW.
CHICAGO YOU'RE ON THE EDGE
OF THAT.
YOU'VE HAD A BIT OF A SNOW
DROUGHT AND LACK OF SNOW,
BREAKING RECORD FOR LONGEST
PERIOD OF TIME YOU HAVEN'T
SEEN SNOW.
YOU COULD SEE SOME OF THAT.
DOESN'T LOOK LIKE YOU WILL
SEE A WHOLE LOT OF IT FROM
THIS NEXT SYSTEM.
SOME OF THAT SNOW MAY STAY
ON THE GROUND FOR CHRISTMAS.
SOME MAY SEE A WHITE
CHRISTMAS BECAUSE OF THE
STORM.
THEBE THE WIND
FACTORED IN WITH THE
SNOWFALL ACCUMULATION AND
THEN YOU'RE LOOKING AT
WINNER STORM WARNINGS IN
EFFECT ACROSS COLORADO, ALSO
UTAH BECAUSE OF THIS STORM
AND DANGEROUS TRAVELING
CONDITIONS ACROSS SOME OF
THOSE MOUNTAIN PASSES,
ACROSS PARTS OF THE ROCKIES,
EVENTUALLY INTO THE PLAINS
AS WE HEAD INTO LATER
WEDNESDAY NIGHT INTO
THURSDAY WE'RE EXPECTING A
POSSIBLE BLIZZARD ACROSS
WESTERN PORTIONS OF KANSAS
INTO NEBRASKA.
THIS WILL BE THE FIRST
SIGNIFICANT SNOWFALL
ACCUMULATION OF THE SEASON.
WE HAVE A NUMBER OF WATCHES
ACROSS THE CENTRAL PLAINS.
EVERYONE STAY ALERT.
TRAVEL WILL BE IMPACTS AS WE
HEAD INTO MIDWEEK AND ALSO
THURSDAY.
BELIEVE IT OR NOT AHEAD OF
THE STORM SYSTEM, JENNA,
TEMPERATURES WILL WARM UP.
WE'LL SEE THUNDERSTORMS AND
POSSIBLE SEVERE WEATHER
TOMORROW.
LARGE HAIL, DAMAGING WIND
AND ISOLATED TORNADOS WILL
BE POSSIBLE ACROSS PORTIONS
OF LOUISIANA, MISSISSIPPI
AND EVEN INTO ARKANSAS.
THIS IS SOMETHING ELSE THAT
WE WILL BE KEEPING AN EYE
ON.
JENNA: GOOD HEAD'S UP FOR US
TODAY, MARIA.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
JON: RIGHT NOW INVESTIGATORS
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, ARE
POURING OVER EVIDENCE AT TWO
CRIME SCENES IN A SEARCH FOR
ANSWERS IN THE DEADLY
SHOOTING AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
SO EXACTLY WHAT ARE THEY
LOOKING FOR AND HOW LONG
WILL THIS INVESTIGATION
TAKE?
BILL DALY IS FORMER FBI
INVESTIGATOR AND SENIOR VICE
PRESIDENT AND PRACTICE
LEADER FOR CONTROL RISKS
SECURITY CONSULTING.
YESTERDAY WE HEARD FROM
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE, HE'S
THE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICEMAN WHO HAS BEEN SORT
OF THE FACE OF THIS
INVESTIGATION, HE SAID WE'RE
GOING TO GET TO THE HARD
DRIVE, WE'LL GET ALL THAT
EVIDENCE OFF HIS COMPUTER
AND WE'RE GOING TO FIND OUT
WHAT WAS BEHIND THIS RAMPAGE.
TODAY WE'RE FINDING OUT THAT
THE COMPUTER HARD DRIVE HAS
BEEN SMASHED APPARENTLY BY
THE GUNMAN BEFORE HE LEFT.
SO DOES THAT MEAN IT'S GOING
TO BE NOT POSSIBLE TO GET
THE INFORMATION?
>> THAT ISN'T NECESSARILY SO,
JON.
THE AREA OF COMPUTER
FORENSICS AND EXAMINATION OF
DAMAGED HARD DRIVES TURNED
INTO A SCIENCE.
IT IS A KEY TOOL IN THE TOOL
BOX FOR INVESTIGATORS THESE
DAYS WITH ALL THE THINGS WE
TOUCH, CRIMINALS TOUCH,
KNOWING WHAT HAPPENS INSIDE
A COMPUTER IS IMPORTANT.
WHAT THEY CAN DO THEY MAY BE
ABLE TO RECREATE PART OF
THAT.
EVEN IF IT IS PHYSICALLY
DAMAGED THERE ARE WAYS TO
RECREATE THE DRIVES.
I WORKED ON CASES WHERE THE
COMPUTERS WERE INVOLVED IN
FIRES.
YOU CAN RETRIEVE INFORMATION
THAT IS HELPFUL.
THEY CAN LOOK AT PERIPHERAL
DEVICES AND BUFFERS AND
MEMORIES.
LOOK AT SEARCH ENGINES,
VARIETY OF THINGS THAT WOULD
HELP PUT THIS PERSON, THE
GUNMAN IN FOCUS.
JON: MAYBE YOUR PRINTER OR
WEB SEARCHES OR GO TO GOOGLE
OR ONE OF THESE OTHER SEARCH
ENGINES AND FIND OUT WHAT HE
WAS UP TO?
>> EXACTLY.
THEY CAN GO OUT TO THAT.
ANY ONLINE MAIL SERVICES.
SEE THOSE TYPE OF ACT
EVIDENT IT IS.
SO IT'S, FOR INVESTIGATORS
THERE REALLY IS KIND OF
POTENTIAL TREASURE TROVE,
POTENTIAL I SAY, FOR THINGS
THAT MAY PUT THIS PERSON,
THIS GUNMAN IN FOCUS.
NOT TO SAY THAT IT WILL AT
THE END OF THE DAY PROVIDE
THE CRYSTAL CLEAR, YOU KNOW,
IMAGE OF WHAT HE WAS UP TO
OR MAYBE EVEN WHAT LED TO
THE TRAGEDY LAST WEEK BUT IT
WILL CERTAINLY PROVIDE SOME
BACKGROUND AND SOME EVIDENCE,
I BELIEVE, TOWARDS WHAT HE
WAS DOING ON AN EVERYDAY
BASIS.
JON: BUT SOME PEOPLE MIGHT
WANT TO ASK, WHY BOTHER?
YOU KNOW THAT THE GUNMAN DID
THIS.
PROBABLY HAD SOME MENTAL
ISSUES.
HE'S DEAD.
WHAT CAN YOU LEARN FROM
PUTTING TOGETHER ALL THE
STEPS HE TOOK GOING UP TO
THAT MOMENT?
>> WELL THERE ARE A COUPLE
OF THINGS.
ONE FROM AN INVESTIGATIVE
STANDPOINT YOU WANT TO MAKE
SURE THERE WERE NO OTHER
PEOPLE WHO WERE AWARE OF
WHAT HE WAS DOING.
JON: THAT HE DIDN'T
COMMUNICATE HIS PLANS TO
ANYBODY?
>> COMMUNICATE TO ANYONE.
ALSO ON THE FORENSIC SIDE
THEY'RE LOOKING AT AS THE
LIEUTENANT MENTIONED ON THE
FIREARMS SIDE.
THEY WANT TO MAKE SURE WHEN
HE WENT TO THE RANGE
ALLEGEDLY TO TO SHOOTING WAS
HE THERE PROPERLY AND
PROPERLY LICENSED.
SOMEWHERE PEOPLE ALONG THE
LINE MAY HAVE LEGAL EXPOSURE
PAUSE OF THINGS THEY SHOULD
HAVE OR SHOULD NOT HAVE
DO.
HOW FAR FROM THAT STANDPOINT,
UNDERSTANDING WHAT HE'S
DOING AND MAN IN FOCUS AS WE
WOULD SAY, UNDERSTAND HOW WE
MIGHT BE ABLE TO PREDICT
THESE THINGS IN THE FUTURE.
YES, WE CAN'T GO BACK AND
CHANGE THE TRAGEDY OF LAST
WEEK.
WE WISH WE COULD.
WE MAY BE ABLE TO PREVENT
THE THINGS IN THE FUTURE
UNDERSTANDING WHAT LED THIS
PERSON.
WHAT WAS THE BACKGROUND?
WHAT WAS HIS MENTAL
CONDITION?
WHAT WAS HIS PHYSICAL
WAS HE ON MEDICATION?
WHO WAS HE COMMUNICATING
WITH?
WHAT THINGS WAS HE LOOKING
AT?
THAT MAY HELP PROFILE FUTURE
CASES.
JON: BILL DALY WITH CONTROL
RISKS SECURITY.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU, JON.
JENNA: JON, WE KNOW SO MANY
VIEWERS ARE LOOKING FOR WAYS
TO HELP.
WE'RE COLLECTING SITES AND
SOURCES FOR YOU WITHIN ON
FOXNEWS.COM.
ONE-STOP SHOP HOW YOU CAN
CONNECT TO NEWTOWN AND
POTENTIALLY GET INVOLVED.
SO MANY OF US ARE LOOKING TO
REACH OUT BECAUSE OF THIS
STORY.
ALSO ONE OF THE THINGS WE'VE
SEEN AS A SIDE STORY, IF YOU
WILL FROM THE MURDERS IN
CONNECTICUT IS THIS
REIGNITED DEBATE OVER GUN
CONTROL IN THIS COUNTRY AND
THE POSSIBILITY OF BRINGING
BACK THE BAN ON ASSAULT
WEAPONS.
WE'RE GOING TO EXPLORE THIS
NEXT.
>>> PLUS, SOME NEW TENSIONS
IN THE MIDDLE EAST AS IRAN
WARNS THAT OUR INVOLVE MANE
WITH NATO AND A NEW MISSILE
SYSTEM MAY SPARK A WORLD
WAR?
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A CLOSER
LOOK AT THAT NEXT.
Hey! Did you know
that Honey Nut Cheerios
has oats that can help lower
cholesterol?
And it tastes good?
Sure does!
Wow.
It's the honey,
it makes it taste so...
Well, would you
look at the time...
What's the rush?
Be happy. Be healthy.
YOU HAVE A PLAN?
FIRST WE'RE GONNA
CHECK OUR BAGS FOR FREE,
THANKS
TO OUR EXPLORER CARD.
THEN, THE UNITED CLUB.
MY MOTR
WAS SO WRONG ABOUT YOU.
NEXT,
WE GET PRIORY BOARDING
ON OUR FLIGHT
I BOOKED WITH MILES.
ALL BECAUSE OF THE CARD.
AND ME.
OKAY, WHAT'S THE PLAN?
PLAN?
MM-HMM.
WE'RE ON VACATION.
THERE IS NO PLAN.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ] THE UNITED
MILEAGEPLUS EXPLORER CARD.
THE MILEAGE CARD
WITH SPECI PERKS ON UNITED.
GET IT AND YOU'RE IN.
JON: RIGHT NOW THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL MASSACRE
REIGNITING THE DEBATE OVER
GUN CONTROL WITH SOME
LAWMAKERS SAYING THAT THE
PRESIDENT SHOULD TAKE THE
LEAD ON THE ISSUE, AT THE
VERY LEAST PUSH FOR
REINSTATING THE ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAND.
OTHERS LIKE A DEMOCRATIC
CONGRESSMAN FROM RHODE
ISLAND SAYS CONGRESS SHOULD
TAKE THE ACTION.
RIGHT NOW HE IS HOLDING A
NEWS CONFERENCE ON GUN
VIOLENCE.
CHIEF WASHINGTON
CORRESPONDENT JAMES ROSEN
LIVE IN OUR D.C. BUREAU WITH
MORE ON THAT.
JAMES?
>> Reporter: JON, GOOD
AFTERNOON.
JANUARY 3rd WILL BE THE
FIRST DAY OF THE NEW
CONGRESS WHEN A LEADING
DEMOCRAT SAYS SHE INTENDS TO
REINTRODUCE A UPDATED
VERSION OF THE ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAND THAT EXPIRED A
DECADE AGO.
SENATOR DIANNE FEINSTEIN,
SENATOR FROM CALIFORNIA,
AUTHOR OF THE ORIGINAL
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN SAYS SHE
HAS WORKED ON IT FOR MOST OF
A YEAR AND WITH IT WILL BE
CAREFULLY PROTECTED TO
PROTECT GUN OWNERS T STOPS
SALE, SPECIFICALLY NAMED
FIREARMS AND SEMIAUTOMATIC
RIFLES, HANDGUNS AND
SHOTGUNS THAT CAN ACCEPT A
DETACHABLE MAGAZINE AND
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLES AND
HANDGUNS WITH A FIXED
MAGAZINE THAT CAN ACCEPT
MORE THAN 10 ROUNDS T STOPS
SALE, TRANSPORTATION
MANUFACTURE OF STRIPS AND
DRUMS CAPABLE OF ACCEPTING
MORE THAN 10 ROUNDS.
TO PROTECT THE GUN OWNERS
THE BILL GRANDFATHERS IN
WEAPONS ALREADY LEGALLY
POSSESSED THE DAY THE BILL
BECOMES LAW.
BANS 9 EXEMPTS 900 WEAPONS
FOR SPORTING OR HUNTING AND
EXEMPTS MAN ALI OPERATED OR
PERMANENT ANY-DISABLED
WEAPONS.
JOE MANCHIN OF WEST VIRGINA
AND MARK WARNER OF VIRGINIA
SIGNALED THEIR OPENNESS TO
NEW GUN REGULATION AND STILL
ANOTHER SENATE DEMOCRAT TOOK
DIRECT AIM TODAY AT THE NRA.
>> IF THE NRA IS SERIOUS
ABOUT GUN VIOLENCE IN THIS
COUNTRY, IF THEY CARE ABOUT
GUN VIOLENCE IN THIS COUNTRY,
EVERYONE WALKING AROUND HERE,
TO WORRIED ABOUT THEIR NRA
SCORED.
THEY SCORED SOTO MY AIR'S
NOMINATION.
THEY SCORED WHETHER THE
ATTORNEY GENERAL WAS HELD IN
CONTEMPT.
I HAVE TWO WORDS FOR THE
NRA.
SCORE THIS.
>> Reporter: UNLIKE THE GUN
CONTROL LAW AND GUN LOBBY
AND SPECIFICALLY THE NRA
HAVE REMAINED SILENT SINCE
NEW TOWN BUT SOURCES CLOSE
TO THE INDUSTRY TELL FOX
NEWS THAT IS SOON GOING TO
CHANGE.
THAT THE NRA WILL SOON START
PUSHING BACK.
SOURCES TO CLOSE TO THE
INDUSTRY TELL FOX NEWS THEY
WILL NOTE JUST FOR STARTERS
THAT COLUMBINE HAPPENED IN
1999, SMACK IN THE MIDDLE OF
THE TEN YEAR PERIOD WHEN
THIS COUNTRY HAD AN ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN.
JON?
JON: JAMES ROSEN IN
WASHINGTON.
THANK YOU, JAMES.
JENNA: NEW INFORMATION NOW
FROM OVERSEAS WHERE TENSIONS
ARE RISING IN THE MIDDLE
EAST.
IRAN'S ARMY CHIEF OF STAFF
IS WARNING WE'RE ALL HEADING
TOWARDS A WORLD WAR.
THIS IS ALL IN REACTION TO
NATO'S RECENTLY ANNOUNCED
DEPLOYMENT OF PATRIOT
MISSILES ALONG TURKEY'S
BORDER.
THESE MISSILES ARE MEANT TO
PROTECT TURKEY FROM THE
POSSIBILITY OF ROCKETS BEING
FIRED FROM SYRIA AS ITS
CIVIL WAR ESCALATES.
WE HAVE FORMER SPOKESMAN FOR
THE LAST FOUR U.S.
AMBASSADORS TO THE UNITED
NATIONS.
RICK, I WANT TO READ THIS
QUOTE FROM THIS GENERAL OUT
OF IRAN SO OUR VIEWERS GET A
FULL IDEA WHAT HE IS SAYING.
QUOTE, EACH ONE OF THESE
PATRIOTS, THESE MISSILES IS
BLACK MARK ON THE WORLD MAP
AND IS MEANT TO CAUSE A
WORLD WAR.
THEY ARE MAKING PLANS FOR A
WORLD WAR AND THIS IS VERY
DANGEROUS FOR THE FUTURE OF
HUMANITY AND FOR THE FUTURE
OF EUROPE ITSELF.
IS THAT BLUSTER OR IS THAT A
SERIOUS THREAT?
>> YOU KNOW I THINK IT COULD
BE A SERIOUS THREAT AND IT
IS ALSO BLUSTER.
I THINK IT'S BOTH.
WHAT WE'RE SEEING IS IRAN
INCREASINGLY PANICKING
BECAUSE OF WHAT IS GOING ON
IN SYRIA.
YOU SEE REPORTS TODAY THERE
ARE JUST THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE
POURING OVER THE BORDER INTO
LEBANON, INTO TURKEY AS
WELL.
JENNA: REFUGEES.
>> THESE ARE REFUGEES OR
OTHERS JUST TRYING TO GET
OUT.
SO ONE CLEAR THING IS THAT
THE IRANIANS HAVE ONE ALLY
IN THE REGION WHICH IS
SYRIA.
IF SYRIA IS NOW IMPLODING
AND ASSAD IS GOING TO BE
DONE I THINK THAT CHANGES
THE WHOLE MAP.
WE'RE ENTERING A WHOLE NEW
PHASE.
I THINK WE, THE UNITED
STATES, WE HAVE TO BE
PREPARED FOR THAT NEW PHASE
OF IRANIANS PANICKING.
JENNA: LET'S TALK A LITTLE
BIT ABOUT THAT BECAUSE IN
THE LAST 21 MONTHS, SEEMS
THE STORY AS WE'VE BEEN
TELLING IT WILL END IF AND
WHEN ASSAD LEAVES OR FALLS.
BUT IT SEEMS LIKE WHAT
YOU'RE SAYING, THAT IS JUST
WHERE THE STORY BEGINS.
>> THAT IS JUST THE
BEGINNING.
WE HAVE IRANIAN ELECTIONS
COMING UP IN JUNE.
THAT I THINK IS A BIG MOMENT
HERE.
THE U.S. GOVERNMENT SHOULD
BE CALLING FOR REGIME
CHANGE.
WE'VE HAD THE WORLD TRYING
TO FIGURE OUT WHICH
OPPOSITION GROUPS IN SYRIA
ARE BEST TO SUPPORT.
WE'VE GONE BACK AND FORTH.
IT HAS TAKEN A LONG TIME.
IT HAS TAKEN 18 MONTHS FOR
THE U.N. TO DECIDE.
HOWEVER IN IRAN WE ALREADY
HAVE AN OPPOSITION GROUP.
THE LARGEST OPPOSITION GROUP
IS ALREADY ORGANIZED.
THEY MEET REGULARLY.
THEY ARTICULATED A POLICY
THAT SAYS WE DON'T WANT A
NUCLEAR WEAPON.
SO WE SHOULD BE SUPPORTING
THAT GROUP.
I THINK THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES, OUR PRESIDENT,
SHOULD SAY, VERY CLEARLY,
THAT WE WANT REGIME CHANGE
IN IRAN.
JENNA: HOW DO WE DO THAT?
BEYOND JUST THE VERY PUBLIC
STATE THAT YOU JUST
MENTIONED, WHAT ELSE CAN BE
DONE?
HOW DOES THE CHAOS IN SYRIA,
MAYBE SET US UP FOR
DIFFERENT STRATEGIES THAN
OTHERWISE IF THAT WASN'T
HAPPENING?
>> WELL I THINK WE'VE GOT TO
BE PREPARED.
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE FINDING
OUT IN SYRIA.
WE'RE SEEING THAT WE WEREN'T
PREPARED.
GROUPS ARE SCRAMBLING AND
AGAIN, WE HAD, YOU KNOW,
EUROPEANS, THE FRENCH AND
BRITISH IT RECOGNIZING THE
SYRIAN OPPOSITION BEFORE WE
DID.
BEFORE THE UNITED STATES
THAT IS NOT GOING TO BE GOOD
FOR THE FUTURE OF SYRIA.
THEY'RE GOING TO REMEMBER
THAT.
SO I THINK WHEN IT COMES TO
IRAN, WE HAVE TO WORK WITH
THOSE GROUPS NOW, HELP THEM
ORGANIZE.
AND TRY TO GET THEM TO THE
POINT WHERE THEY COULD TAKE
OVER IMMEDIATELY PEACEFULLY.
LET'S TRY TO DO IT WITHOUT A
WAR.
JENNA: HOW DO WE DO THAT IN
SUCH A CLOSED COUNTRY?
>> WITH THE ELECTIONS IT IS
A GREAT OPPORTUNITY.
RIGHT NOW WE HAVE SIX MONTHS
TO REALLY FIGURE OUT HOW WE
SUPPORT THE GREEN
REVOLUTION.
PRESIDENT OBAMA DIDN'T DO IT
LAST TIME.
HE WILL HAVE TO REALLY LOOK
FOR SIGNS.
I THINK THEY'RE ALREADY
HAPPENING RIGHT NOW WHERE
THE OPPOSITION IS BEGINNING
TO RAISE THEIR HEAD AND SAY,
WE'D LIKE TO OVERTHROW OUR
GOVERNMENT.
CAN YOU HELP?
THAT'S WHEN WE CAN JUMP IN.
WE'VE GOT TO MAKE SURE
TWITTER AND THE INTERNET IS
NOT BLOCKED SO THAT PEOPLE
CAN ORGANIZE.
WE HAVE TO HELP THEM WITH
ARMS IF THEY HAVE, IF THEY
NEED THEM.
JENNA: YOU'RE SAYING BE VERY
AGGRESSIVE HERE?
>> BE VERY AGGRESSIVE WITH
ORGANIZATION.
MUCH LIKE WE'RE DOING IN
SYRIA NOW EVEN THOUGH IT
TOOK A LONG TIME.
JENNA: SOME SAY IF WE TAKE
AWAY AHMADINEJAD, WHO IS THE
PRESIDENT THERE NOW WE DON'T
DO MUCH BECAUSE THE
AYATOLLAH.
>> THE SUPREME LEADER
CONTROLS FOREIGN POLICY.
JENNA: HOW DO YOU NAVIGATE
THAT?
>> THE NATIONAL ELECTIONS IS
FOR AHMADINEJAD'S POSITION.
I THINK WHAT YOU HAVE TO DO
IS CREATE INSTABILITY OR
HELP THE INSTABILITY THAT'S
ALREADY THERE AND REALLY
PUSH THEM FORWARD BECAUSE IT
IS ALREADY THERE.
WE JUST HAVE TO TAP IN.
JENNA: A LITTLE BIT COUNTER
INTUITIVE THIS POLICY.
COMFORTABLE WITH CHAOS
BECAUSE CHAOS COULD LEAD TO
ONE OF THE MOST ORGANIZED
RESULTS EVENTUALLY HOPEFULLY
IN OUR BEST INTERESTS.
>> WE DON'T HAVE PEACE RIGHT
NOW.
IT MIGHT APPEAR TO BE STABLE
BUT IT IS NOT PEACEFUL.
THESE PEOPLE DON'T
EXPERIENCE PEACE INSIDE IRAN.
JENNA: NICE TO HAVE YOU ON
SET WITH US.
PLEASURE ALWAYS TO HAVE YOU
ON THE PROGRAM.
>> THANKS.
JENNA: JON?
JON: JUST IN AN UPDATE ON
ONE OF THE STRANGER MEDIA
EVENTS I'VE CERTAINLY SEEN
IN MY CAREER.
THAT IS THE SCANDAL THAT LED
TO THE RESIGNATION OF FORMER
FOUR-STAR ARMY GENERAL AND
CIA DIRECTOR-GENERAL DAVID
PETRAEUS.
ACCORDING TO THE ASSOCIATED
PRESS PAULA BROAD WELL, THE
TAMPA SOCIALITE WILL NOT BE
PROSECUTED FOR E-MAILS SHE
SENT TO JILL KELLEY.
THE JUSTICE DEPARTMENT
LOOKED INTO WHETHER THE
E-MAILS THAT BROADWELL SENT
TO KELLY WARNINGER HAD TO
STAY AWAY FROM THE MARRIED
GENERAL.
I SHOULD MENTION BROADWELL
WAS MARRIED AS WELL AS WAS
KELLY.
THOSE E-MAILS DID NOT AMOUNT
TO CYBER STALKING.
ACCORDING TO THE JUSTICE
DEPARTMENT AS REPORTED BY
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS.
SO FOR NOW, PAULA BROADWELL
IS OFF THE HOOK AT LEAST IN
THAT PART OF THIS VERY
STRANGE CASE.
WE'LL KEEP YOU UPDATED.
>>> THERE ARE NEW
DEVELOPMENTS IN THE FISCAL
CLIFFHANGER WITH THE
WHITE HOUSE REJECTING HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER'S PLAN
B.
THAT JUST HAPPENED WITHIN
THE LAST 40 MINUTES.
ALL THIS AS REPUBLICAN
LAWMAKERS NOW MAKE THE CASE
FOR BOOSTING REVENUE THROUGH
TAX REFORM.
ONE OF THEM WILL BE HERE
LIVE TO EXPLAIN WHY HE
THINKS THAT IS THE FISCALLY
CONSERVATIVE APPROACH.
PLUS, REMEMBERING SENATOR
INOUYE, THE WAR HERO WHO
BECAME ONE OF THE LONGEST
SERVING SENATORS IN AMERICAN
HISTORY.
HOW HIS LEGACY STRETCHED FAR
BEYOND HIS HOME STATE OF
HAWAII.
THAT'S NEXT
JENNA: WELL THAT WAS QUICK.
WE HEARD FROM JOHN BOEHNER,
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER EARLIER
TODAY SAYING HE HAD A PLAN B
FOR THE FISCAL CLIFF
COMPROMISE.
HE WOULD PUT FORWARD
LEGISLATION SO THAT ANYONE
EARNING LESS THAN A MILLION
DOLLARS WOULD NOT SEE THEIR
TAXES GO UP AT THE END OF
THE YEAR.
WELL THE WHITE HOUSE CAME
OUT AND OFFICIALLY SAID NO
TO PLAN B.
WE WERE HERING FROM JAY
CARNEY.
OF COURSE THE PRESS
SECRETARY FOR THE PRESIDENT
SAYING THE SPEAKER'S PLAN B
APPROACH DOESN'T MEET THIS
TEST OF A BALANCED APPROACH
BECAUSE IT CAN'T PASS THE
SENATE AND THEREFORE WILL
NOT PROTECT THE MIDDLE
CLASS.
GOES ON IN THE STATEMENT TO
SAY BASICALLY, GAME ON.
AS ED HENRY TOLD US COME ON
PLAN-C, RIGHT?
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE LOOKING
FOR.
PLAN A IS NOT WORKING OUT SO
WELL BECAUSE NEGOTIATIONS
ARE NOT MAKING A LOT OF
PROGRESS, BABY STEPS.
PLAN B SPEAKER PUT FORWARD
TODAY, REJECTED BY THE
WHITE HOUSE.
SO MAYBE PLAN-C, JON, PLAN-C.
JON: AS YOU WELLPOINTED OUT.
JENNA: HERE GOING TO TALK A
LITTLE BIT MORE WHAT THIS
ALL MEANS NOW.
JON: WHAT A WAY TO RUN A
COUNTRY, HUH?
>>> THERE IS A NEW CALL FOR
RAISING TAX REVENUE OR
INCREASING REVENUE AND IT
COMES AMID EFFORTS TO HAMMER
OUT A DEAL ON THE SO-CALLED
FISCAL CLIFF.
REPUBLICAN CONGRESSMAN SCOTT
REQUIRING GEL, OUTSPOKEN
CRITIC OF ANTI-TAX PLEDGE IS
LAYING OUT THE CONSERVATIVE
CASE BOOSTING TAX REVENUE
THROUGH TAX REFORM.
THE CONGRESSMAN JOINS US
NOW.
HE SERVES ON THE HOUSE
HOMELAND SECURITIES SERVICES
COMMITTEE.
CONGRESSMAN RIGEL, YOU WROTE
A LETTER TO EVERY SINGLE
MEMBER OF CONGRESS AND SAID
YOU'RE UP FOR BOOSTING TAX
REVENUE?
>> WELL, JON, THANK YOU FOR
HAVING ME ON THE SHOW.
AMERICA HAS A SPENDING
PROBLEM PRINCIPALLY AND MY
VOTES REFLECT A DEEP RESOLVE
TO CAST A DIFFICULT VOTE TO
REDUCE FEDERAL SPENDING BUT
I'M A BUSINESSMAN IN MY
FIRST ELECTED OFFICE.
A CAREFUL REVIEW OF OUR TAX
CODE AND ITS YIELD OVER 12
YEARS REALLY MAKES CLEAR TO
ME THAT AS REPUBLICANS ARE
LOCKING OURSELVES INTO THIS
CURRENT TAX CODE THROUGH THE
AMERICANS FOR TAX REFORM
PLEDGE HAVE LOCKED US INTO A
LEVEL OF REVENUE THAT WE'VE
NOT REDUCED
WHAT IT MEANS FOR ME TO BE A
CONSERVATIVE, A FISCAL
CONSERVATIVE, TO MAKE SURE
WE VOTE FOR A LEVEL OF
REVENUE THAT AT LEAST
MATCHES THE LEVEL OF
EXPENDITURES WE OURSELVES
HAVE VOTED FOR.
JON: YOU HAVE OFFERED OR
SUGGESTED RAISING WHAT, $800
BILLION THROUGH CLOSING THE
LOOPHOLES?
ISN'T THAT WHAT CONGRESSMAN
BOEHNER, SPEAKER BOEHNER
OFFERED TO THE WHITE HOUSE
AND WAS REJECTED SO FAR?
>> WELL, YES.
I REALLY BELIEVE THAT
CAPPING DEDUCTIONS IS THE
FIRST PLACE WE'VE GOT TO GO
IN REFORMING OUR TAX CODE.
PART OF THE APPEAL, JON IS
THE SIMPLICITY OF IT.
YOU CAN JUST IMPLEMENT IT,
FOR EXAMPLE, LIKE A $50,000
CAP.
THAT IS HYPOTHETICAL NUMBER
BUT IT REALLY DOES GENERATE
THE REVENUE THAT WE NEED TO
AT LEAST PAY FOR THE LEVEL
OF EXPENDITURES THAT WE
OURSELVES AS REPUBLICANS
HAVE VOTED FOR.
AND THAT'S WHY I'M IN
SUPPORT OF THE SPEAKER'S
EFFORTS TO BOTH REDUCE
SPENDING AND ALSO HAVE A
MODEST LEVEL OF INCOME
INCLUDED IN AN OVERALL
AGREEMENT.
JON: WILL YOU BE OPEN TO AN
INCREASE IN TAX RATES, FOR
INSTANCE THE HIGHEST
EARNERS?
PRESIDENT OBAMA SAYS THOSE
MAKING MORE THAN $250,000 A
YEAR SHOULD PAY MORE.
>> WELL WHAT I'M DOING RIGHT
NOW IS I AM ADVOCATING FOR
AN AGREEMENT THAT IS
SIMULTANEOUS.
THAT MEANS REDUCING FEDERAL
SPENDING AND ALSO HAVING
REVENUES RISE A LITTLE BIT.
WHEN IT COMES DOWN TO ASKING
MY, EXACTLY WHAT I WOULD
VOTE ON, I REALLY NEED TO
RESERVE JUDGMENT ON THAT
BECAUSE I NEED TO SEE WHAT
THE TOTAL AGREEMENT IS.
WHAT ARE WE DOING, FOR
EXAMPLE, WITH RESPECT TO THE
DEBT LIMIT?
IT WOULD BE A GREAT CONCERN
OF MINE IF THE DEBT LIMIT IS
INCORPORATED INTO THIS
AGREEMENT.
I THINK THAT NEEDS TO BE
SEPARATE.
SO THOSE ARE THE KIND OF
THINGS I'LL BE LOOKING FOR
AND IT'S REALLY A DYNAMIC
ENVIRONMENT, JON.
WE JUST LEARNED THIS MORNING
OF COURSE OF THE PLAN B
OPTION.
JON: YEAH.
THAT APPARENTLY HAS GONE
AWAY, BEEN REJECTED BY THE
WHITE HOUSE WITHIN THE LAST
HOUR.
REPRESENTATIVE SCOTT RIGELL
IN HIS FIRST TERM FROM
VIRGINIA.
GOOD TO TALK TO YOU THIS
MORNING.
LET US KNOW IF YOU GET A
CHRISTMAS CARD FROM GROVER
NORQUIST.
>> THANKS SO MUCH.
JENNA: A RESPONSE FROM THE
SPEAKER BOEHNER'S OFFICE TO
THE WHITE HOUSE SAYING NO
DEAL ON PLAN B.
SAYING THE WHITE HOUSE'S
POSITION DEFIES COMMON SENSE
AND GOES ON.
AFTER WE GO THROUGH THE BACK
AND FORTH BETWEEN
REPUBLICANS AND DEMOCRATS,
THE BIGGED HEADLINE HERE
THAT NEITHER PLAN OUT THERE
REALLY ADDRESSES SOME OF THE
MAJOR FISCAL CONCERNS IN
THIS COUNTRY.
JON: RIGHT.
JENNA: WE'LL WATCH THE BACK
AND FORTH ON THIS, THAT'S
THE BIG HEADLINE TO REMEMBER
AS WE MOVE FORWARD INTO THE
NEW YEAR.
JON: TILTING AT WINDMILLS.
JENNA: YEAH, RIGHT NOW.
WE'LL KEEP YOU POSTED ON THE
BACK AND FORTH.
BE RIGHT BACK WITH MORE
"HAPPENING NOW"
JON: TODAY WE REMEMBER ONE
OF THE LONGEST-SERVING
SENATORS IN THIS NATION'S
HISTORY.
HERE'S BRET BAIER.
>> DANIEL INOUYE REPRESENTED
HAWAII IN CONGRESS FROM THE
TIME IT BECAME A STATE IN
1959.
HE WAS INITIALLY ELECTED AS
THE STATE'S FIRST HOUSE
MEMBER FOR TWO TERMS.
SUBSEQUENTLY AS SENATOR FOR
NINE TERMS.
BUT HIS STORIED TENURE BEGAN
AS A FRESHMAN HOUSE MEMBER.
BY THE END OF HIS CAREER,
INOUYE WAS THE MOST SENIOR
MEMBER OR PRESIDENT PRO-TEM
IN THE SENATE, MAKING HIM
THIRD IN LINE FOR THE
PRESIDENCY.
INOUYE PREFER AD REFERENCE
FOR THE INSTITUTION OF THE
SENATE OVER THE PARTISAN
BOMBASTS DISPLAYED BY MANY
OF HIS COLLEAGUES.
ALTHOUGH HE RARELY APPEARED
AT PRESS CONFERENCES OR MADE
SPEECHES ON THE SENATE FLOOR
HE HAD UNDENIABLY COMMANDING
PRESENCE.
HIS WORDS TENDED TO CARRY
WEIGHT WHEN HE DID SPEAK OUT
ON ISSUES.
HE CHAIRED FOUR DIFFERENT
COMMITTEES DURING HIS SENATE
TENURE.
THE INTELLIGENCE COMMITTEE,
THE INDIAN AFFAIRS COMMITTEE,
THE COMMERCE COMMITTEE AND
THE APPROPRIATIONS
COMMITTEE.
INOUYE AASSUMED THE HELM OF
THAT PANEL AFTER LEGENDARY
SENATOR ROBB BIRTH BYRD
RELINQUISHED THE GAVEL.
HE WAS A WITNESS TO THE
PEARL HARBOR ATTACK AND WAS
THE FIRST JAPANESE-AMERICAN
TO SERVE IN EITHER CHAMBER
OF COMMERCE.
HE HAD THE DISTINCTION OF
SERVING IN THE 4450th
REGIMENTAL COMBAT TEAM A
SEGREGATED UNIT OF JAPANESE
AMERICANS IN WORLD WAR II.
THE MOST DECORATED UNIT IN
AMERICAN HISTORY.
>> THE BOMBING OF PEARL
HARBOR 70 YEARS AGO BEGAN A
PERIOD OF MY LIFE WHEN HE
BECAME AN ADULT.
AND I HOPE THEN A GOOD
AMERICAN.
>> THE THEN WAR DEPARTMENT
INITIALLY DETERMINED THAT
THE SECOND GENERATION
JAPANESE AMERICANS WERE
ENEMY ALIENS, PROHIBITED
FROM SERVING IN THE MILITARY.
>> NONE OF THEM HAD
COMMITTED ANY CRIME.
INVESTIGATION AFTER
INVESTIGATION DISCLOSED
THAT.
NO SABOTAGE, NO ESPIONAGE,
NO ASSAULT, NOTHING.
BUT THEY WERE ROUND UP AND
PLACED INTO THESE CAMPS.
>> AFTER INOUYE AND OTHER
FELLOW NISI SUCCESSFULLY
PETITIONED THE ROOSEVELT
ADMINISTRATION TO CHANGE THE
POLICY THE ADMINISTRATION
BEGAN TO ACCEPT THEM ON
LIMITED BASIS.
>> PRESIDENT ROOSEVELT
ISSUED A STATEMENT THAT
AMERICAN SYSTEM NOT A MADDER
OF BLOOD OR COLOR.
AMERICAN SYSTEM A MATTER OF
HEART AND SOUL.
>> INOUYE WAS PROMOTED TO A
SERGEANT IN HIS FIRST YEAR
AND EVENTUALLY BECAME A
PLATOON LEADER.
WHILE FIGHTING NAZI FORCES
IN TUSCANY IN APRIL 1945.
INOUYE SUFFERED MULTIPLE
INJURIES AND HAD HIS ARM
AMPUTATED.
HE EARNED 16 MEDALS AND
CITATIONS FOR HIS SERVICE
INCLUDING THE DISTINGUISHED
SERVICE CROSS, THE BRONZE
STAR, THE PURPLE HEART AND
MEDAL OF HONOR BUT HE WASN'T
AWARD THE LAST RECOGNITION
UNTIL 2000.
NONE OF THE SOLDIERS OF THE
442nd REGIMENT EVER RECEIVED
THE MEDAL OF HONOR, THE
MILITARY'S HIGHEST
DECORATION.
MORE THAN 50 YEARS LATER THE
DISTINGUISHED SERVICE
CROSSES GIVEN TO INOUYE AND
21 MEMBERS OF THE REGIMENT
WERE UPGRADED TO A MEDAL OF
HONOR.
INOUYE WAS IN THE SPOTLIGHT
IN THE 1970s MEMBER OF THE
WATERGATE COMMITTEE PROBING
THE ACTIVITIES OF THE NIXON
ADMINISTRATION.
>> WOULD YOU CARE TO
RECOMMEND TO THIS COMMITTEE
ANY LEGISLATION TO PREVENT
THE REOCCURRENCE OF SOME OF
THE IRREGULARITIES THAT
OCCURRED IN THE 1972
PRESIDENTIAL ELECTION?
>> IN 1987 HE CHAIRED
ANOTHER CONGRESSIONAL PANEL
INVESTIGATING EXECUTIVE
BRANCH WRONGDOING,
IRAN-CONTRA COMMITTEE.
>> I WILL MISS HIM.
THAT IS A GROSS
UNDERSTATEMENT.
>> HE LIVE AD REMARKABLE
AMERICAN LIFE, FILLED WITH
DIGNITY AND GRACE OF THE
TRUE HERO THAT HE WAS.
>> DANIEL INOUYE WAS 88.
IN WASHINGTON, BRET BAIER,
FOX NEWS
[ Woman ]
Ring. Ring.
Progresso.
I just finished a bowl of your
new Light Chicken Pot Pie Soup
and it's so rich
and creamy...
is it really 100 calories?
Let me put you on webcan...
...lean roasted chicken...
and a creamy broth
Mmm
I can still see you.
[ Male announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
JON: RIGHT NOW A FUNERAL
UNDERWAY FOR ONE OF THE CHILDREN
MURDERED IN THE SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL MASSACRE.
AS THE NEWS MEDIA COME UNDER
SCRUTINY FOR ROUND THE CLOCK
COVERAGE OF THE STORY.
DOES MEDIA ATTENTION REALLY
INSPIRE COPYCAT CRIMES?
>>> A FORMER MARINE CHAINED TO A
BED IN A MEXICAN PRISON, ARREST
ED FOR WHAT HIS PARENTS
ARE SAYING IS AN ADMINISTRATIVE
MISTAKE.
>>> AND YOU MIGHT LIKE TO TOSS
BACK A LITTLE CHRISTMAS CHEER
OVER THE HOLIDAYS.
WHY WINE MAKERS ARE SAYING THE
FISCAL CLIFF FIGHT IS MAKING
THEIR DECEMBER ALL THE MERRIER.
SOMEBODY'S HAPPY.
BRAND NEW STORIES AND BREAKING
NEWS ALL "HAPPENING NOW."
JON: A SOMBER DAY IN A TOWN
SHATTERED BY EVIL, FILLED WITH
GRIEF.
TWO MORE OF THE 20 CHILDREN
MURDERED IN THEIR CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL BEING LAID TO REST TODAY.
THIS IS A BRAND NEW HOUR OF
"HAPPENING NOW," I'M JON SCOTT.
JENNA: HI, EVERYBODY, I'M JENNA
LEE, AND GETTING BACK TO NORMAL
MAY SEEM ALL BUT IMPOSSIBLE FOR
THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN,
ESPECIALLY TODAY, AS MOURNERS
SAY GOOD-BYE TO MORE INNOCENT
LIVES LOST.
WHILE INVESTIGATORS EXAMINE THE
SCHOOL AND THE GUNMAN'S HOME FOR
EVIDENCE, FOLKS ARE STRUGGLING
TO RETURN TO THEIR DAILY
ROUTINES.
SOME OF THE TOWN'S OTHER SCHOOLS
REOPENING TODAY WITH STEPPED-UP
SECURITY, BUT IT'S HARD TO
IGNORE THE PAINFUL PROCESSION OF
FUNERALS.
YOU HAVE TWO MORE TINY CASKETS
ARRIVING TODAY AT ST. ROSE.
RIGHT NOW A SERVICE IS GETTING
UNDERWAY FOR JESSICA REKOS,
JAMES MAN GOALLY WAS BURIED
EARLIER TODAY.
THEY WERE BOTH JUST 6 YEARS OLD.
PETER DOOCY'S LIVE IN NEWTOWN
WITH MORE ON ALL OF THIS.
MANY STUDENTS WENT BACK TO
SCHOOL TODAY.
WE TALK ABOUT GETTING BACK TO
NORMAL, WHATEVER THAT MEANS
RIGHT NOW IN NEWTOWN.
HOW IS IT GOING?
>> Reporter: RIGHT NOW THINGS
ARE NOT BACK TO NORMAL IN
NEWTOWN, JENNA.
WE ACTUALLY SAW THIS MORNING
SOME OF THOSE BUSES TAKING
STUDENTS BACK TO SCHOOL, AND
THEY DROVE VERY SLOWLY WITH
EVERY STUDENT LOOKING OUT THE
WINDOW RIGHT PAST THIS MEMORIAL
TO THEIR FALLEN NEIGHBORS.
AND AT THIS MEMORIAL THE RAIN
HAS LEFT THOUSANDS OF LETTERS
AND FLOWERS WET, BUT PEOPLE ARE
STILL COMING BY TO PAY THEIR
RESPECTS.
SOMEONE EVEN LEFT CARTOON
CHARACTER PUZZLES RECOMMENDED
FOR AGES 3-8, THE SAME RANGE AS
EVERY SINGLE FIRST GRADE VICTIM.
ONE WOMAN EVEN CAME BY TO LEAVE
A TEDDY BEAR, AND SHE BROKE
DOWN.
>> I HAVE A CHILD.
I DIDN'T LOSE ANYBODY DIRECTLY,
BUT IT'S AFFECTING ME DIRECTLY
BECAUSE I'M A MOM.
I COULDN'T IMAGINE THE LOSS OF A
CHILD.
I'M TRYING TO LET GO OF THE
BEAR.
>> Reporter: MOVING TRUCKS
HAULING SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL'S FURNITURE HAVE DRIVEN
BY HERE SEVERAL TIMES AS WELL.
SO AT THIS CHRISTMAS TREE,
JENNA, NOBODY IS TALKING ABOUT
SANTA CLAUS, THEY ARE LITERALLY
WEEPING IN THE STREETS FOR SANDY
HOOK.
JENNA: AND, PETER OR, STILL
TRYING TO PIECE TOGETHER SO MUCH
OF WHAT TRANSPIRED ON FRIDAY.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT WHAT
ELSE WE MAY HAVE LEARNED ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED INSIDE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL?
>> Reporter: JENNA, THE FAMILY
OF 6-YEAR-OLD DYLAN HOCKLEY SAY
THEIR SON, WHO HAD SPECIAL
NEEDS, DIED IN THE ARMS OF THE
AIDE HE ADORED, ANN MARIE
MURPHY, AND THEY SAY HE TAKE
GREAT COMFORT IN KNOWING HE DID
NOT DIE ALONE.
THIS COMES, AS YOU MENTIONED, AS
TWO OF HIS CLASS MATES TODAY ARE
HAVING FUNERAL SERVICES.
JAMES MATTIOLI'S JUST WRAPPED
UP, JESSICA REKOS' IS JUST
BEGINNING AT THE SAME CHURCH.
JENNA?
JENNA: PETER, THANK YOU.
WE'RE JUST GETTING A BREAKING
NEWS REPORT AS WELL OUT OF
CONNECTICUT, SPECIFICALLY OUT OF
NEWTOWN.
SOME LOCAL STATIONS ARE
INVESTIGATING THIS.
THERE IS APPARENTLY A LOCKDOWN
AT ONE OF THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS
THERE.
NO STUDENTS INSIDE.
WANT TO BE VERY CLEAR ABOUT
THAT.
BUT APPARENTLY THIS MORNING AT
HEADOW MEADOW ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
POLICE DECIDED TO CLOSE IT AS A
PRECAUTIONARY MEASURE.
IT WAS SUPPOSED TO OPEN WITH ALL
THE OTHER SCHOOLS, WE DON'T KNOW
WHY POTENTIALLY THIS SCHOOL HAS
CLOSED DOWN.
AGAIN, NO STUDENTS INSIDE THE
SCHOOL, POLICE ARE INVESTIGATING
X WE'RE TRYING TO GET MORE
INFORMATION ON THAT.
CERTAINLY, EMOTIONS HIGH IN THE
AREA, AND PRECAUTIONARY MEASURES
WILL BE TAKEN AS WE HEARD
DIRECTLY FROM THE STATE
OFFICIALS YESTERDAY.
SO WE'LL KEEP YOU POSTED AS WE
HEAR MORE.
JON: THE MASS SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT SPARKING A NATIONAL
DEBATE AND POSSIBLY A SHIFT IN
THE POLITICS OF GUN CONTROL.
SOME LAWMAKERS INCLUDING
OUTSPOKEN GUN RIGHTS ADVOCATES
ARE WILLING TO CONSIDER, THEY
SAY, NEW RESTRICTIONS ON
ASSAULT-STYLE WEAPONS.
WEST VIRGINIA SENATOR JOE
MANCHIN, A DEMOCRAT AND AN AVID
HUNTER, SAYING IT'S TIME TO
CONSIDER REASONABLE RESTRICTIONS
ON GUNS.
VIRGINIA SENATOR MARK WARNER,
ALSO A DEMOCRAT, SAYS THE
SHOOTING HAS LED HIM TO RETHINK
HIS OPPOSITION TO A BAN ON
ASSAULT WEAPONS.
AND REPUBLICAN SENATOR CHUCK
GRASSLEY OF IOWA IS CALLING FOR
A COMMISSION TO STUDY THE
SHOOTINGS, BUT HE SAYS IT SHOULD
INCLUDE MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES AND
NOT JUST BE ABOUT GUNS.
LET'S TALK ABOUT IT WITH BRET
BAIER, THE ANCHOR OF "SPECIAL
REPORT."
WE GOT SOME INDICATIONS IN THE
MESSAGE THAT THE PRESIDENT HAD
TO SHARE REALLY WITH THE NATION
AT THAT MEMORIAL SERVICE THAT HE
WOULD BE INTERESTED IN PUSHING
FORWARD WITH SOME KIND OF GUN
CONTROL, BUT HE'S BEEN VERY
SHORT ON SPECIFICS THUS FAR.
>> WELL, THAT'S RIGHT, JON.
NOT SPECIFIC POLICY PROPOSALS.
THE ONLY ONE THAT IS PRETTY
SPECIFIC SO FAR UP ON CAPITOL
HILL IS FROM SENATOR DIANNE
FEINSTEIN WHO HAS THE OUTLINES
OF A BILL READY TO GO FOR THE
NEW CONGRESS, A BILL THAT WOULD
ESSENTIALLY INSTITUTE THE
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN BACK FROM
THE MID '90s AND ALSO HAVE
SOME VERY STRICT RESTRICTIONS ON
THE AMMUNITION, THE ROUNDS, THE
CLIPS, THE AMOUNT OF ROUNDS IN A
CLIP.
AND IT'S VERY SPECIFIC BUT ALSO
GRANDFATHERS IN A NUMBER OF
WEAPONS.
THAT'S A PIECE OF LEGISLATION
THAT FEINSTEIN SAYS SHE'LL PUT
UP.
YOU MENTIONED SOME OF THESE
LAWMAKERS, DEMOCRATS -- ALL --
JOE MANCHIN, MARK WARNER FROM
VIRGINIA, KIRSTEN GILLIBRAND
FROM NEW YORK.
ALL OF THEM PRO-GUN LAWMAKERS,
ALSO WE SHOULD POINT OUT THE
SENATE MAJORITY LEADER, HARRY
REID, IS BACKED BY THE NRA, HAS
A PRO-GUN LEGISLATIVE HISTORY
AND HAS ALSO SIGNALED THAT HE,
TOO, WANTS TO MOVE FORWARD WITH
SOMETHING.
HOW THIS MOVES FORWARD, I THINK,
IS REALLY THE QUESTION.
AND THE COMMISSION IS OFTEN A
WAY THAT WASHINGTON DEALS WITH
BIG, CONTROVERSIAL THINGS.
THAT MAY ACTUALLY BE ATTRACTIVE
TO SOME FOLKS AND SOME
REPUBLICANS WHO REALLY WANT
MENTAL HEALTH TO BE CONSIDERED
AS WELL AS VIDEO GAMES AND
HOLLYWOOD'S IMPACT ON OUR
CULTURE.
JON: WHITE HOUSE SPOKESMAN JAY
CARNEY HAS BEEN ASKED ABOUT THAT
AND WHAT GUN CONTROL PLAYS IN
THE COMPREHENSIVE SOLUTION.
LET ME PLAY THAT EXCHANGE FOR
YOU, BRET.
>> IN THE COMPREHENSIVE
SOLUTION, DO YOU THINK IT'S FAIR
AND ACCURATE TO SAY THAT
ADDRESSING GUN VIOLENCE, GUN
CONTROL WOULD HAVE TO BE PART OF
IT?
>> I THINK THAT IT'S PART OF IT,
BUT IT IS FAR FROM ALL OF IT,
AND AS YOU KNOW, THE PRESIDENT
HAS TAKEN POSITIONS ON COMMON
SENSE MEASURES THAT HE BELIEVES
SHOULD BE TAKEN TO HELP ADDRESS
THIS PROBLEM, BUT HE MADE CLEAR
THAT MORE NEEDS TO BE DONE, THAT
WE AS A NATION HAVE NOT DONE
ENOUGH, CLEARLY, TO FULFILL OUR
NUMBER ONE OBLIGATION WHICH IS
TO PROTECT OUR CHIRP.
OUR CHILDREN.
JON: IT SEEMS THAT, YOU KNOW,
PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS POLITICAL
CAPITAL RIGHT NOW.
HE WON RE-ELECTION.
IF HE WANTS GUN CONTROL, IT
SEEMS LIKE HE SHOULD BE A LITTLE
MORE FORCEFUL IN TALKING ABOUT
IT.
>> WELL, I THINK IN COMING DAYS
YOU MAY SEE MORE PUSH FROM THE
WHITE HOUSE ON THIS, AND I THINK
YOU'LL DEFINITELY SEE THE ALLIES
IN THE SENATE LIKE SENATOR
FEINSTEIN MOVE THIS FORWARD.
AND I THINK WHEN YOU'RE STARTING
TO HEAR AND SEE SOME OF THESE
LAWMAKERS WHO HAVE TRACK RECORDS
OF REALLY PUSHING BACK ON ANY
EFFORT OF GUN CONTROL IN THE
PAST LIKE MANCHIN WHO YOU MAY
REMEMBER RAN IN A CAMPAIGN AT
ONE POINT RUNNING AN AD IN THAT
CAMPAIGN FIRING A RIFLE AT A
CLIMATE CHANGE BILL, YOU KNOW, I
MEAN, THIS IS A GUY THAT RAN
TOUTING HIS GUN-OWNING AND
HUNTING SKILLS AS PART OF HIS
CAMPAIGN.
WHEN HE STARTS TALKING ABOUT THE
NEED FOR CHANGE, YOU START TO
SEE A DIFFERENT TAKE ON THINGS.
AT LEAST IN THE MIDDLE.
IT'LL BE INTERESTING TO SEE THE
PUSHBACK WHEN THE NRA GETS
INVOLVED, AND I THINK THAT
YOU'LL SEE THAT --
JON: RIGHT.
>> -- IN COMING DAYS.
JON: THEY HAVE STAYED LARGELY
SILENT, ENTIRELY SILENT, BUT
THEY SAY THEY ARE APPARENTLY
ABOUT TO PUSH BACK.
STICK AROUND WITH US, BRET, WE
HAVE ANOTHER BIG STORY IN
WASHINGTON TODAY, JENNA HAS THAT
FOR US.
JENNA: NEW DEVELOPMENTS THAT ARE
REALLY ONLY EMPHASIZING THE OLD
STATUS QUO STANDOFF OVER THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
THE WHITE HOUSE JUST MOMENTS AGO
REJECTING SPEAKER BOEHNER'S
BACK-UP PROPOSAL SAYING IT
DOESN'T PUT ENOUGH OF A TAX
BURDEN ON THE WEALTHIEST
AMERICANS.
THE BACK AND FORTH AND BACK AND
FORTH AND HERE WE GO AGAIN.
CHIEF POLITICAL CORRESPONDENT
CARL CAMERON IS LIVE ON CAPITOL
HILL.
SO, CARL, WHAT IS EXACTLY
HAPPENING OVER THERE?
>> Reporter: WELL, MR. BOEHNER
HAS COME UP WITH AN ALTERNATIVE
PROPOSAL, AND THEY ARE
ESSENTIALLY WORRIED THAT THE
FISCAL CLIFF -- WHICH IS A
TWO-PART THING, MASSIVE, MASSIVE
SPENDING CUTS AND HUGE TAX
INCREASES.
IF THE PRESIDENT WON'T COME TO
THE REPUBLICAN SIDE AND REDUCE
SPENDING MORE AGGRESSIVELY,
MR. BOEHNER SAYS THEY WILL
CONTINUE TO NEGOTIATE, BUT THERE
NEEDS TO BE A SO-CALLED PLAN B
IN WHICH REPUBLICANS ARE
OFFERING TO DEAL WITH TAX CUTS
AND RAISE THEM ONLY ON INCOMES
OVER A MILLION DOLLARS FROM THE
CURRENT 35% TO THE CLINTON ERA
39.6%.
SPENDING VERSUS TAX CUTS, AND
REPUBLICANS DON'T LIKE WHAT
THEY'RE HEARING, SO THEY NEED A
PLAN B.
LISTEN.
>> SO AT THE SAME TIME THAT
WE'RE GOING TO CONTINUE TO TALK
WITH THE PRESIDENT, WE'RE GOING
TO ALSO MOVE PLAN B.
I THINK WE ALL KNOW THAT EVERY
INCOME TAX FILER IN AMERICA IS
GOING TO PAY HIGHER RATES COME
JANUARY THE 1ST UNLESS CONGRESS
ACTS.
>> WE LOOK TO FIND THE ANSWER TO
SOLVE THE PROBLEM ON THE
SPENDING ISSUE HERE IN
WASHINGTON.
THE PRESIDENT IS NOT YET THERE,
HE HAS NOT COME TO WHERE HE
NEEDS TO BE IN ORDER FOR US TO
PUSH THROUGH A BILL THAT REALLY
DOES BEGIN TO ADDRESS THE
PROBLEM.
AND CAN AS THE SPEAKER SAID --
AND AS THE SPEAKER SAID, THAT'S
WHY WE ARE NOW DISCUSSING AN
ALTERNATIVE PLAN IF THE
PRESIDENT AND THE WHITE HOUSE
CANNOT COME OUR WAY.
>> Reporter: SO REPUBLICANS
INSIST THEY ARE GOING TO
CONTINUE TO NEGOTIATE IN GOOD
FAITH, BUT THEY'RE CONCERNED
THAT THE PRESIDENT HASN'T
COMPROMISED ENOUGH ON REAL
SERIES SPENDING REDUCTIONS --
SERIOUS SPENDING REDUCTIONS, HAS
THEM OFFERING NOT A NEW
COUNTEROFFER, BUT A PLAN B
SHOULD NEGOTIATIONS ON THE
OVERALL DEAL BREAK DOWN.
AND THAT, THEY SAY, WOULD DEAL
ONLY WITH THE TAX CUTS.
THE WHITE HOUSE IS UTTERLY
OBJECTING IT AND, FRANKLY,
THEY'RE TRYING TO CAST IT AS A
COUNTEROFFER.
THEY'RE SAYING THIS IS WHAT THE
REPUBLICANS ARE NOW TALKING
ABOUT, TO ONLY DEAL WITH THE TAX
HIKE PROBLEM AND IGNORE
SPENDING.
REPUBLICANS DENY THAT, THEY'RE
STILL AT THE TABLE, AND THIS IS
WHAT WE'RE LOOKING AT WITH TIME
RAPIDLY RUNNING OUT BEFORE THE
COUNTRY'S ECONOMY GOES OVER THAT
CLIFF AFTER THE FIRST OF THE
YEAR.
JENNA: ALL RIGHT.
JUST AFTER NOON EAST COAST TIME,
WE HAVE PLAN B ON AND OFF THE
TABLE.
WE'LL SEE IF WE GET PLAN C.
CARL, THANK YOU.
JON: BRET BAIER, ALL OF THIS
BACK AND FORTH ON THE FISCAL
CLIFF AND THE PROFFER OF A PLAN
B FROM REPUBLICANS, THE WHITE
HOUSE HAS ALREADY SHOT IT DOWN
OR SO IT WOULD SEEM.
UM, WHAT ARE THE CHANCES OF
GETTING SOMETHING DONE HERE?
>> WELL, I MEAN, THEY'RE
STARTING TO DIMINISH AS WE RUN
OUT OF DAYS, AND REMEMBER
THERE'S STILL THE TIME THAT'S
NEEDED TO PUT THE WHATEVER DEAL
COMES TOGETHER INTO LEGISLATIVE
LANGUAGE.
THAT TAKES TIME.
THERE'S SAUSAGE MAKING THAT'S
INVOLVED IN ACTUALLY PUTTING IT
TO PAPER IN THE BIG DOME BEHIND
ME.
SO YOU REALLY RUN OUT OF TIME
HERE.
SO THAT'S WHY AS YOU SAW WITH
THE DEBT CEILING BACK AND FORTH
LAST YEAR, THE REPUBLICANS ARE
DOING ANOTHER TRACK, THIS PLAN
B, TO GET THINGS MOVING IF, IF A
DEAL DOESN'T COME TOGETHER.
SO IT DOESN'T LOOK GOOD AT THIS
POINT.
IT DOESN'T LOOK LIKE THE WHITE
HOUSE IS MOVING.
IT DOES LOOK LIKE DEMOCRATS ARE
REJOICING THAT THE REPUBLICANS
ARE HAVING SUCH ANGST WITHIN
THEIR OWN PARTY, AND THEY ARE.
CONSERVATIVES HAVE A REALLY HARD
TIME WITH EVEN SPEAKER BOEHNER
TALKING ABOUT ONE MILLION PLUS
TAX HIKES WITHOUT SEEING THE
SPENDING MOVEMENT ON THE WHITE
HOUSE SIDE.
SO THE BIG THING, THE BOTTOM
LINE HERE IS THAT WHATEVER DEAL
IS STRUCK, YOU STILL HAVE TO GET
THE VOTES TO GET IT THROUGH BOTH
CHAMBERS.
AND IN THE HOUSE THAT'S 218
VOTES, AND A LOT OF THEM ARE
CONSERVATIVES WHO DO NOT WANT TO
MOVE UNLESS THERE IS SOME
SIGNIFICANT SPENDING CUTS TIED
TO THIS DEAL.
JON: SO JOHN JOHN BOEHNER HAS A
LOT OF CATS TO HERD, OR SO IT
WOULD SEEM.
>> DEFINITELY.
JON: THANKS VERY MUCH, BRET
BAIER.
"SPECIAL REPORT" THE BEST
COVERAGE OF ALL THINGS
WASHINGTON AND POM TICKS --
POLITICS MONDAY THROUGH FRIDAY,
6 P.M. EASTERN.
JENNA: NEW CONCERNS THAT ROUND
THE CLOCK MEDIA COVERAGE OF THE
SCHOOL SHOOT ANYTHING
CONNECTICUT MAY INSPIRE COPYCAT
KILLERS.
WE WANTED TO TALK ABOUT IT TODAY
WITH OUR NEWS WATCH PANEL AHEAD.
PLUS, TRAINING HOW TO RESPOND IN
THE EVENT OF A TERRORIST ATTACK.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE YOU BEHIND
THE SCENES TO A FACILITY WHERE
OUR FIRST RESPONDERS ARE
LEARNING HOW TO TAKE DOWN THE
BAD GUYS.
THAT'S NEXT.
♪
[ loud party sounds ]
HI,
I'M Ensure Clear...
Clear, HUH?
I'M NOT JUICE OR FANCY WATER.
I'VE GOTINE GRAMS OF PROTEIN.
THAT'S THREE TIMES MORE THAN ME!
[ Female Announcer ]
Ensure Clear.
NINE GRAMS PROTEIN. ZERO FAT.
IN BLUEBERRY/POMEGRANATE
AND PEACH.
JENNA: WELCOME BACK, EVERYONE.
WANT TO UPDATE YOU ON SOME NEWS
WE JUST TOLD YOU ABOUT ABOUT
ANOTHER ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, BEING
CLOSED BECAUSE OF A POTENTIAL
THREAT ACCORDING TO LOCAL
REPORTS.
WE HAVE SENT A CREW ON THE SCENE
TO THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL ALSO
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, BUT
APPARENTLY POLICE ARE KEEPING US
A BLOCK AWAY.
JUST A REMINDER, ALL OF THE
SCHOOLS DO HAVE OFFICERS AT
THEIR LOCATIONS TODAY BECAUSE
MANY OF THEM ARE REOPENING FOR
THE FIRST TIME AFTER FRIDAY'S
SHOOTING.
ACCORDING TO ONE LOCAL NEWS
STATION IN CONNECTICUT, POLICE
APPARENTLY CLOSED THIS SCHOOL
BECAUSE OF PRECAUTIONARY
REASONS.
WFSB SAYS THIS LETTER WAS SENT
TO PARENTS BY THE PRINCIPAL IN
THIS MORNING SAYING, QUOTE: AS
WAS PREDICTED BY THE POLICE THAT
THERE WOULD BE SOME THREATS, THE
POLICE WERE PREPARED AND HAVE US
IN LOCKDOWN WHICH IS OUR NORMAL
PROCEDURE, AGAIN, ACCORDING TO
THE PRINCIPAL.
STUDENTS WILL NOT COME TO SCHOOL
TODAY, PLEASE MAKE ARRANGEMENTS
TO KEEP THEM AT HOME.
THERE ARE NO STUDENTS IN THIS
SCHOOL, APPARENTLY THERE ARE
SOME STAFF ON THE SCENE, BUT
AGAIN, JUST A REPORT AT THIS
TIME.
UNFORTUNATELY, WE HEARD FROM THE
STATE POLICE YESTERDAY,
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE, WHO SAID,
LISTEN, WE'VE BEEN GETTING
THREATS OF AFTER THE PAST COUPLE
DAYS, AND WE'RE GOING TO GO
AFTER THESE PEOPLE WHO ARE
MAKING THESE TYPE OF THREATS TO
OUR COMMUNITY IN ANY STRETCH OF
THE IMAGINATION THAT THEY'RE
DOING THIS.
WE'LL KEEP YOU POSTED.
AGAIN, ONE SCHOOL, HEADOW MEADOW
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL THIS
NEWTOWN -- IN NEWTOWN CLOSED FOR
PRECAUTIONARY REASONS THIS
MORNING.
JON: LET'S TAKE YOU DOWN TO
GEORGIA NOW.
LAW ENFORCEMENT IS TAKING ON
TERRORISTS.
OFFICERS AT THE GEORGIA FACILITY
LEARN TO COMBAT TERRORISTS'
EVER-CHANGING STRATEGIES FROM
CYBER WARFARE TO HANDLING
WEAPONS OF MASS DESTRUCTION.
STEVE HARRIGAN LIVE IN
BRUNSWICK, GEORGIA, WITH MORE
FOR US.
STEVE?
>> Reporter: JON, WATCHING
THESE COUNTERTERRORISM EXERCISES
CAN REALLY GET YOUR
HEARTBEATING, AND THAT'S THE
GOAL, IS TO TAKE THESE FEDERAL
RESPONDERS AND PUT THEM IN
SITUATIONS OF REAL PRESSURE.
>> LET'S GO.
[GUNFIRE]
>> Reporter: AT THE FEDERAL
LAW ENFORCEMENT TRAINING CENTER
IN BRUNSWICK, GEORGIA, THEY USE
BLANK AMMUNITION --
>> POLICE!
>> Reporter: -- BUT REAL
ACTORS.
>> YOU CAN'T SIMULATE BEHAVIOR.
YOU HAVE TO USE PEOPLE TO
SIMULATE BEHAVIOR.
>> Reporter: 60,000 FEDERAL
AGENTS A YEAR COME TO THE
1600-ACRE SITE COMPLETE WITH
MOCK AIRPLANES, A TEST
TRACK.
THE IMPORTANT THING IN
PERFORMING A PIT MANEUVER IS
LOCATION.
NO EMBANKMENTS, NO BRIDGES AND
NO CON CONGESTION.
TERROR ATTEMPTS FROM THE PAST
ARE REHEARSED ALONGSIDE
POTENTIAL FUTURE ATTACKS LIKE
IMPROVISED EXPLOSIVE DEVICES.
>> WE WANT TO PREPARE
DOMESTICALLY FOR ANY TYPE OF
THREAT, AND WE WANT TO BE ABLE
TO DEFEAT THAT THREAT SHOULD IT
OCCUR HERE IN THE UNITED STATES.
>> WE NEED BACKUP.
>> Reporter: RESPONSE
TRAINING, THOUGH, TO ABDUCTIONS
OR ACTIVE SHOOTERS IS ONLY PART
OF THE MISSION.
>> WE CAN'T AFFORD TO JUST
RESPOND TO INCIDENTS ANYMORE.
WE HAVE TO PREVENT THINGS FROM
HAPPENING.
>> Reporter: NOW, DIRECTOR,
AFTER LAST WEEK'S SHOOTINGS, A
LOT OF PEOPLE ARE ON EDGE UNDER
THE -- AROUND THE COUNTRY.
HOW THAT IS THAT AFFECTED TO
WHAT YOU ARE DOING HERE?
>> IT REINFORCES WHY TRAINING IS
SO IMPORTANT, AND IT ALSO
INSPIRES US TO DO A BETTER JOB.
>> Reporter: A REAL SENSE OF
URGENCY HERE.
JON AND JENNA, BACK TO YOU.
JON: WOW, THAT LOOKS LIKE A
FASCINATING PROGRAM.
STEVE HARRIGAN, THANKS.
JENNA: WOW.
WELL, B THAT NEW HEALTH CARE LAW
MEANS NEW REGULATIONS, WE KNOW
THAT, BUT IS THE GOVERNMENT
MOVING TOO QUICKLY TO PUT THEM
INTO EFFECT?
A LOT IN THE NEXT YEAR OR SO, SO
WE'RE GOING TO GET YOU UPDATED
ON THE LATEST THERE.
>>> ALSO, A PLAN TO SAVE MONEY
COULD PUT CITIZENS TO WORK DOING
JOBS CURRENTLY HANDLED BY
POLICE.
IS THAT REALLY THE SAFEST
OPTION?
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE A LIVE
REPORT AHEAD.
QUESTIONS?
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME R CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
♪
JENNA: NEW REGULATIONS CREATED
BY THE PRESIDENT'S HEALTH CARE
LAW ARE NOW ON THE FAST TRACK
AND, APPARENTLY, SOME WATCHDOG
GROUPS SAY THE NEW RULES ARE
BEING IMPLEMENTED SO QUICKLY,
OPPONENTS ARE NOT GETTING ENOUGH
TIME TO REALLY WEIGH IN.
THAT'S WHAT THEY SAY.
SHANNON BREAM IS LIVE IN
WASHINGTON WITH THE LATEST NOW.
SHANNON?
>> Reporter: HI, JENNA.
WELL, AS YOU KNOW, WHEN CONGRESS
PASSES A LAW, IT'S BASICALLY
JUST A FRAMEWORK, AND THEN
FEDERAL AGENCIES ARE DELEGATED
THE AUTHORITY TO WRITE
REGULATIONS AND RULES THAT SPELL
OUT JUST HOW THE LAW WILL BE
ENFORCED.
BEFORE THEY BECOME FINAL,
THERE'S A COMMENT PERIOD WHEN
THE PUBLIC, EMPLOYERS,
COMPANIES, ANYONE WHO MAY BE
IMPACTED CAN WEIGH IN.
BACK IN 1993 PRESIDENT CLINTON
STATED THAT AGENCIES SHOULD
ALLOW AT LEAST A 60-DAY COMMENT
PERIOD, BUT THAT'S NOT WHAT'S
HAPPENING WITH FOUR NEW
REGULATIONS TIED TO THE HEALTH
CARE LAW.
THREE OF THEM HAVE A 30-DAY
COMMENT PERIOD, THE FOURTH HAS
JUST 24 DAYS WITH THE FINAL
COMMENT DUE THE DAY AFTER
CHRISTMAS.
AMERICANS FOR LIMITED GOVERNMENT
HAS WRITTEN TO THE DEPARTMENT OF
HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES ASKING
FOR AN EXPLANATION AND
REQUESTING THAT THE COMMENT
PERIOD BE EXTENDED.
ONE OF THE REGULATIONS IS MORE
THAN 400 PAGES LONG, AND
REGULATORY EXPERTS SAY IT WOULD
BE NEARLY IMPOSSIBLE FOR A
COMPANY TO REVIEW SOMETHING OF
THAT VOLUME AND PREPARE A FORMAL
COMMENT IN TIME.
>> BECAUSE OF THAT, A LOT OF
THESE AGENCIES WORK IN SECRET.
THE ONLY PEOPLE THAT KNOW ABOUT
THEM ARE LARGE STAKEHOLDERS AND
INDUSTRY THAT HAVE FULL-TIME
COUNSEL THAT DO NOTHING BUT LOOK
AT THESE THINGS.
BUT THERE ARE A NUMBER OF
REGULATIONS THAT ARE PUBLISHED
EACH AND EVERY DAY IN THE
FEDERAL REGISTER THAT AFFECT
YOUR DAILY LIFE, AND IT'S
DEFINITELY WORTH LOOKING AT
BECAUSE IF YOU DON'T PAY
ATTENTION TO IT, THEN THIS IS A
WHOLE PART OF THE GOVERNMENT
THAT'S OPERATING IN SECRET
OTHERWISE.
>> Reporter: AND BY THE WAY,
ACCORDING TO THE GOVERNMENT'S
OWN WEB SITE, THERE HAVE BEEN
NEARLY 6,000 FEDERAL REGULATIONS
PROPOSED JUST IN THE LAST R 90
DAYS.
WE REACHED OUT TO BOTH THE WHITE
HOUSE AND HHS, AND SO FAR NO
RESPONSE.
JENNA?
JENNA: WE'LL LOOK FORWARD TO
THAT WHEN WE GET IT, SHANNON.
THANK YOU.
JON: A MARINE VETERAN CHAINED TO
A BED IN ONE OF MEXICO'S MOST
DANGEROUS PRISONS.
HE'S WAITING ON A JUDGE'S
DECISIONS THAT COULD MAKE IT
MUCH MORE DIFFICULT TO GET HIM
OUT.
THE LATEST ON HIS CASE AND HIS
PARENTS' DESPERATE PLEA FOR HIS
RELEASE.
>> EXAMINE THIS CASE.
THIS IS WRONG, AND DO THE RIGHT
THING.
HE SHOULD BE RELEASED
IMMEDIATELY.
THIS WAS AN ADMINISTRATIVE
MISTAKE.
HE IS NOT A GUN RUNNER, AND YOU
KNOW IT.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
♪ BUT THE FIRE IS
SO DELIGHTFUL ♪
NOTHING MELTS AWAY THE COLD
LIKE A HOT, DELICIOUS BOWL
OF CHICKEN NOODLE SOUP
FROM CAMPBELL'S.
♪ LET IT SNOW, LET IT SNOW
JON: RIGHT NOW WE'RE GETTING
OUR FIRST LOOK AT MARINE
VETERAN JOHN HAMMAR SINCE
HIS ARREST IN MEXICO BACK IN
AUGUST.
THE PHOTO SENT ANONYMOUSLY
TO HIS FAMILY SHOWS HAMMAR
CHAINED TO HIS BED IN ONE OF
MEXICO'S MOST DANGEROUS
PRISONS.
HE FACES WEAPONS CHARGES
BRINGING HIS FATHER'S
ANTIQUE SHOTGUN INTO MEXICO
EVEN THOUGH DELAYED IT AT
THE BORDER.
HE WENT ON THE RECORD LAST
NIGHT DISCUSSING HIS SON'S
EFFORT TO GET THE VETERAN
FREED WITH "ON THE RECORD"
WITH GRETA VAN SUSTEREN.
>> BEHIND THE SCENES WE'RE
TALKING WITH OUR ATTORNEY TO
THE MEXICAN ATTORNEY
GENERAL.
WE KNOW CONGRESSWOMAN
ROS-LEHTINEN HAS BEEN IN
TOUCH WITH MEXICAN OFFICIALS
BUT WE'RE FRUSTRATED, YES.
JON: ERIC SHAWN IS ON THIS
CASE.
HE JOINS US LIVE WITH THE
LATEST.
ERIC?
>> Reporter: JON, HE SERVED
IN IRAQ AND AFGHANISTAN BUT
NOW FORMER U.S. MARINE
VETERAN JOHN HAMMAR AS YOU
SAID TAKE A LOOK, IN A
MEXICAN PRISON CHAINED TO
THAT BED IN WHAT HIS FAMILY
CALLS A CLERICAL ERROR.
HE WAS ON HIS WAY TO HUNT
AND SURF IN COSTA RICA.
WHEN THEY ARRIVED IN MEXICO
THEY WERE ARRESTED FOR
BRINGING IN A ILLEGAL
WEAPONS.
HIS MOTHER SAID THE GUN IS
100-YEAR-OLD AT TEEN --
ANTIQUE BELONGED TO HIS
GREAT GRAND FATHER.
HE WANTED TO GO BIRD
HUNTING.
BUT THE BARREL WAS TOO SHORT
UNDER LEGAL LIMITS.
SHE IS DEVASTATED.
>> JOHN ANY MADE AN
ADMINISTRATIVE MISTAKE.
HE DIDN'T REGISTER.
HE SHOULD HAVE REGISTERED
THE GUN AT AN EMBASSY IN THE
UNITED STATES BEFORE GOING
OVER THERE.
SO BASICALLY HE HAS BEEN IN
JAIL FOR FOUR MONTHS CHAINED
TO A BED OVER A CLERICAL
ERROR.
>> Reporter: ANTIQUE OR NOT
IT IS ILLEGAL TO IMPORT GUNS
INTO THE COUNTRY WHICH IS
WHY JOHN FACES THE CHARGES.
HE TOLD HIS MOTHER HE HASN'T
BEEN CHAINED TO HIS BED THE
WHOLE TIME.
HASN'T BEEN CHAINED SINCE
LAST WEDNESDAY.
MEXICAN AMBASSADOR TO THE
UNITED STATES SAID IT WAS
FOR SECURITY REASONS.
IN THE LETTER JOHN WAS PUT
QUOTE, IN AN ADMINISTRATIVE
AREA TO INSURE HIS SAFETY.
LACK OF CELLS IN THE AREA OR
ANY SECURITY MEASURES THERE
LEFT AUTHORITIES WITH NO
OTHER CHOICE BUT TO
TEMPORARILY RESTRAIN OR
LIMIT HIS MOVEMENT.
DOING IT WITH THAT CHAIN.
WELL THE U.S. STATE
DEPARTMENT WHICH SAYS
AMERICANS ARE ARRESTED
MEXICO EVERY YEAR FOR GUN
POSSESSION HAVE VISITED
JOHN.
THEY'RE KEEPING TABS ON HIS
PLIGHT.
HIS NEXT COURT DATE IS THE
MIDDLE OF JANUARY WHICH
MEANS HE WILL LIKELY STILL
BE IN PRISON, JON, ON
CHRISTMAS.
JON: WHAT A TRAGEDY.
LET'S HOPE THEY GET THE GUY
OUT OF THERE.
ERIC SHAWN, THANK YOU.
JENNA: WE'LL TALK HOW TO DO
THAT NOW.
WE'LL BRING IN FOX LEGAL
ANALYST, LIS WIEHL AND TED
SIMON AN INTERNATIONAL
ATTORNEY THAT REPRESENTED
AMANDA FOX AND NAVIGATED THE
MEXICAN COURT SYSTEM AS
WELL.
WELCOME TO YOU BOTH.
TED, THAT IS THE BIG
QUESTION.
WHY CAN'T WE GET THIS GUY
OUT OF PRISON NOW?
>> UNFORTUNATELY TOO MANY
AMERICANS AND UNFORTUNATELY
FOR THIS YOUNG MAN THEY
DON'T REALIZE THE AMERICAN
CONSTITUTION DOES NOT TRAVEL
WITH THEM FOR A FOREIGN
COUNTRY AND IS NOT TO BE
THEIR ADVOCATE.
WE FORGET THE MAXIM WHEN IN
ROME DO AS ROMANCE DO AND
ABIDE BY LAWS OF FOREIGN
COUNTRIES.
THIS IS SAD STORY.
HE WAS VERY OPEN.
DECLARED THE GUN ON U.S.
SIDE AND WENT IN THERE.
PROBABLY SHOULD HAVE BEEN
MORE PRUDENT AND DONE THE
SAME SORT OF THING WITH THE
MEXICAN EMBASSY HERE BUT AS
FAR AS GETTING HIM OUT, THE
WAY IT WORKS THERE DECIDEDLY
DIFFERENT THAN IN THE U.S.
INITIALLY THEY WILL LOOK AT
THE EVIDENCE AND IF THE
POLICE THINK'S THERE'S A
SUFFICIENT BASIS TO CHARGE
THEY WILL.
HE IS THEN BROUGHT BEFORE
THE MINISTER WHICH HAS 48
HOURS TO DETERMINE IF THERE
IS SUFFICIENT EVIDENCE OR
EXTEND THE TIME.
THEREAFTER THE JUDGE HAS 72
HOURS TO DETERMINE IF THERE
IS SUFFICIENT CAUSE.
NOW IT APPEARS THIS MUST
HAVE HAPPENED BECAUSE HE HAS
BEEN IN FOR THAT PERIOD OF
TIME ALTHOUGH I'M NOT
FAMILIAR WITH THE DETAILS.
HE DOES HAVE ALTERNATIVES.
THERE IS CERTAIN PROPERLY
MECHANISMS IN MEXICO.
YOU CAN FILE A EMPARO
WHETHER OR NOT YOUR RIGHTS
ARE VIOLATED.
JENNA: SORRY TO INTERRUPT,
BASED ON WHAT YOU'RE SAYING,
DO YOU THINK IT IS LIKELY OR
UNLIKELY THAT HE GETS OUT OF
PRISON IN JANUARY?
HE COULD BE, ACCORDING TO
THE LATEST THAT WE HAVE,
SOME OF HIS OFFENSES COULD
BE PUNISHABLE UP TO 15 YEARS
IN PRISON.
DO YOU THINK THAT IS LIKELY,
THAT HE STAYS IN PRISON
LONGER THAN THE TIME HE
ALREADY HAS SPENT?
>> I WOULDN'T WANT TO
PREJUDGE THE CASE BUT THERE
IS ENOUGH MITIGATING FACTS
HERE I THINK IN THE END, YOU
KNOW, FAIRNESS WILL PREVAIL.
AND I THINK, WHILE HE IS
CHARGED WITH THE MOST
SERIOUS, IT DOESN'T MEAN IT
HAS TO STAY THERE.
THERE SEEMS TO BE A CONFLICT
IN TYPES OF CHARGES.
HE IS CHARGED WITH AN
AGGRAVATED FELONY FOR BEING
IN POSSESSION OF A WEAPON
THAT THE MILITARY USES.
ON THE OTHER HAND IT APPEARS
THERE ARE STATUTES IN PLACE
THAT PERMIT THE POSSESSION
AS LONG AS IT IS NOT SHORTER
THAN 20 INCHES.
WE UNDERSTAND HIS GUN IS AT
LEAST 24.
JENNA: AS HE POINTS OUT,
VERY CONFUSING EVEN SOME
DETAILS WE HAVE WHAT EXACTLY
HE IS BEING HELD ON.
>> RIGHT.
JENNA: WHAT OTHER KIND OF
DETAILS TO THIS CASE HIS
PARENTS, AS WELL AS THE
YOUNG MAN WHO WAS WITH HIM,
WHO WAS ARRESTED AS WELL BUT
NOT KEPT IN PRISON BECAUSE
IT WASN'T HIS GUN, SAY WHEN
THEY TALKED TO THE U.S.
AGENTS THEY TOLD HIM, GO
AHEAD, YOU'LL BE FINE.
>> YOU'LL BE FINE.
THE BARREL OF THE SHOTGUN IS
24 INCHES.
UNDER, FORGET ABOUT THE U.S.
CONSTITUTION I AGREE IT DOES
NOT APPLY IN MEXICO
OBVIOUSLY BUT, 24 INCH
BARREL, RIGHT.
WHAT THEY PROSECUTE IN
MEXICO FOR THE MOST HEINOUS
CRIMES ARE 20 INCHES AND
BELOW.
WHY WOULD MEXICO BE GOING
OUT OF ITS WAY TO PROSECUTE
THIS YOUNG MAN, KEEP HIM IN
PRISON FOR UP TO 15 YEARS,
JENNA.
IT JUST DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
I WILL TELL YOU THE PARENT
HAVE GONE ON THE RECORD SAID
IT IS NOT ABOUT THE GUN.
IT IS ABOUT EXTORTION FROM
THE PARENTS.
PARENTS ALLEGING THEY HAVE
BEEN CALLED AND SAID YOU PAY
UP, YOU WIRE US MONEY OR
ELSE.
JENNA: THIS PRISON, TED, IS
SUPPOSEDLY RUN BY ONE OF THE
BIGGEST AND MOST DANGEROUS
CARTELS IN THE AREA THE
PARENTS HAVE SAID THIS.
WHAT LISA SAID ABOUT
EXTORTION, HOW DO YOU KEEP A
CLIENT LIKE THIS SAFE?
>> THIS IS ONE OF THE
FUNDAMENTAL DIFFERENCES WHEN
REPRESENTING AN AMERICAN IN
A FOREIGN COUNTRY.
NOT ONLY DO YOU HAVE TO
PROTECT AND TRY TO PREVAIL
IN THE CASE YOU HAVE TO BE
CONCERNED WITH THEIR VERY
SURVIVAL.
THE AMERICAN EMBASSY WILL BE
CONCERNED ABOUT HUMANITARIAN
VIOLATIONS, WILL BE ABLE TO
WEIGH ON THOSE TYPES OF
ISSUES BUT WILL NOT BE ABLE
TO WEIGH IN AS AN ADVOCATE.
AND I THINK THE PARENT AS
LONG AS THEY CONTINUE TO
REMAIN PERSUASIVE AND NOT
INSULTING AND RAISE THIS
ISSUE TO THE PUBLIC I THINK
IT'S PROBABLY A WORTHWHILE
WAY TO ADVANCE HIS CAUSE.
AGAIN, ONE HAS TO BE CAREFUL
WHEN DEALING WITH THE MEDIA
IN THESE SORTS OF THINGS.
THIS IS THE KIND OF CASE
THAT SHOULD WORK ITSELF OUT
WITH THE PROPER
DOCUMENTATION.
>> CAN'T THE AMERICAN
EMBASSY THOUGH, YOU'RE
SAYING THEY SHOULD STAY OUT
OF IT PRETTY MUCH I DON'T
THINK THAT IS CORRECT
BECAUSE THE AMERICAN EMBASSY
CAN SAY TO THE MEXICO
GOVERNMENT, THE PROSECUTION,
HEY, ABIDE BY YOUR OWN
GUIDELINES.
YOU DON'T PROSECUTE FOR THE
15 YEAR PENALTY UNLESS 20
INCHES AND BELOW.
JENNA: TED WHAT ABOUT THAT?
WHAT IS THE RISK I GUESS,
THE POLITICAL INVOLVEMENT?
>> SURE, SURE.
THIS IS A VERY DELICATE
DANCE THAT GOES ON AND
REALLY VARIES FROM CASE TO
CASE.
ON THE ONE HAND THE AMERICAN
GOVERNMENT WILL BE THE FIRST
TO SAY THEY ANT BE YOUR
ADVOCATE AND CAN'T GET YOUR
RELEASE.
ON THE OTHER HAND THERE ARE
DIPLOMATIC CHANNELS THAT CAN
BE EMPLOYED, HOSTEN EMPLOYED
PUBLICLY AND NOT SO
PUBLICLY.
THAT IS THE ART OF DEALING
WITH THESE SORTS OF CASES.
ONE HAS TO BE CAREFUL WHAT
THEY'RE SAYING PUBLICLY TO
INSURE THE BEST POSSIBLE
RESULT.
I BELIEVE IN THE END THIS IS
THE SORT OF CASE IF PROPERLY
HANDLED WILL RESOLVE ITSELF
AND HE SHOULD BE RETURNED TO ST.
IT'S CLEAR HE HAD NO BAD
INTENT.
HE DECLARED IT ON THE U.S.
SIDE.
HE DECLARED IT ON THE
MEXICAN SIDE.
BUT FOR NOT HAVING THE
PROPER PERMIT THIS WOULD IN
THE HAVE HAPPENED.
AGAIN IT'S A REMINDER FOR
EVERYONE LISTENING IF YOU'RE
GOING TO TRAVEL TO A FOREIGN
COUNTRY, CONSIDER WHAT
YOU'RE GOING TO BE DOING
THERE, WHAT YOU'RE GOING TO
BE BRINGING WHAT YOU'RE
GOING TO ACQUIRE AND WHAT
YOU WILL BRING BACK.
JENNA: GOOD ADVICE FOR
SOMEONE WHO REPRESENT AD FEW
HIGH-PROFILE CASES OVERSEAS.
LIS, QUICK FINAL THOUGHT.
>> BOTTOM LINE HE SHOULD
HAVE HAD A SMALL FINE AND
BEEN RELEASED.
CRAZY HE IS IN PRISON FOUR
MONTHS IN SOLITARY
CONFINEMENT.
JENNA: THANKS TO YOU BOTH.
IT IS A STORY WE'LL CONTINUE
TO WATCH.
FOX NEWS LATINO HAS BEEN AT
THE FOREFRONT OF THE STORY.
THEY GOT THE PICTURE OWN
YOUR SCREEN.
CHECK IN FOR BREAKING
DEVELOPMENTS ON POSITION
NEWS LATINO.COM.
JON: A TERRIBLE STORY
UNFOLDING IN COLORADO RIGHT
NOW.
HEATHER NAUERT IS GETTING
NEW INFORMATION AT OUR
BREAKING NEWS DESK, HEATHER?
>> Reporter: AT THIS HOUR
POLICE NEAR LONG MONTH,
COLORADO, 30 MILES NORTH OF
DENVER ARE INVESTIGATING A
GRUESOME CRIME SCENE THAT
UNFOLDED WHILE A 911
DISPATCHER WAS ON THE PHONE
WITH A WOMAN WHO WOULD SOON
BECOME A VICTIM.
AND HERE'S A LOOK AT THAT
SITE RIGHT NOW.
AUTHORITIES IN COLORADO SAY
THAT AT LEAST FOUR PEOPLE
WERE FOUND DEAD INSIDE THIS
HOME IN AN APPARENT
MURDER-SUICIDE.
A COLORADO POLICE DISPATCHER
TELLING REPORTERS THAT A
CALL CAME IN TO 911 ABOUT
4:00 A.M. MOUNTAIN TIME
TODAY.
A WOMAN ON THE OTHER END OF
THE LINE GAVE HER HOME
ADDRESS AND THEN SHE
SCREAMED INTO THE PHONE, NO,
NO, NO.
WHAT FOLLOWED THEN WAS A
SERIES OF GUNSHOTS.
A MAN THEN PICKED UP THE
PHONE TELLING THE DISPATCHER
THAT HE PLANNED TO KILL
HIMSELF.
THE DISPATCHER ON THE PHONE
THEN HEARD A GUN GO OFF.
THE WELLS COUNTY S.W.A.T.
TEAM WAS CALLED INTO THE
SCENE AND THEY ENTERED THAT
HOUSE FINDING FOUR PEOPLE,
TWO MEN AND ONE WOMAN DEAD.
A POLICE SPOKESMAN SAYING
THAT THREE OF THE VICTIMS
ARE ADULTS.
ONE VICTIM MAY BE IN HER
EARLY TEENS OR IN HER LATE
20s.
THEIR IDENTITIES HAVEN'T
BEEN RELEASED JUST YET BUT
WE KNOW NO ONE ELSE WAS
FOUND IN THAT HOME.
NEIGHBORS DESCRIBING THIS AS
A GOOD, PEACEFUL PLACE, A
NICE NEIGHBORHOOD.
POLICE PLAN TO HOLD A PRESS
CONFERENCE LATER TODAY.
WE'LL KEEP YOU POSTED ON THE
DELAYS OF THIS DISTURBING
STORY.
JON?
JON: I SPENT A SUMMER
WORKING FOR A RADIO STATION
IN LONGMONT.
A GREAT COMMUNITY.
>> Reporter: HARD TO HEAR.
JON: HEATHER, THANKS.
JENNA: WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
GUN CONTROL IN THE WAKE OF
THE MURDERS IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
ONE OF THE OTHER STORIES
WE'RE WATCHING GUN SALES
THAT HAVE APPARENTLY
INCREASED SINCE WHAT WE'VE
SEEN TRANSPIRE OVER THE LAST
FEW DAYS IN NEW TOWN.
WHAT EXPLAINS THIS RUSH AND
TYPE OF FIREARMS THAT ARE
REALLY BEING SOLD RIGHT NOW?
WE'LL TELL YOU A LITTLE BIT
ABOUT THAT.
>>> PLUS AS CITIES PLAN TO
BUILD POLICE POSTS WITH
CIVILIANS WOULD SAVE A LOT
OF MONEY BUT IS IT WHAT IS
MOST SAFE FOR THE COMMUNITY
THERE?
JENNA: WELCOME BACK,
EVERYONE.
"HAPPENING NOW", THERE'S A
PLAN TO HIRE CIVILIANS TO
TAKE JOBS HELD BY POLICE.
THE CITY OF DENVER, COLORADO,
SAYS IT COULD SAVE MORE THAN
A HALF MILLION DOLLARS A
YEAR BY DOING THIS.
MORE IMPORTANTLY, PUT MORE
POLICE OFFICERS ON THE
STREETS.
NOT EVERYONE IS HAPPY WITH
THE IDEA.
ALICIA ACUNA IS LIVE FROM
DENVER WITH MORE.
ALICIA?
>> Reporter: JENNA, THAT'S
RIGHT.
THE DENVER POLICE UNION SAYS
THERE ARE JOBS ONLY AN
OFFICER CAN DO BUT THE CHIEF
INSISTS THIS WILL HELP HIS
DEPARTMENT AND ITS BOTTOM
LINE.
>> WE HAVE IDENTIFIED
APPROXIMATELY 45 POSITIONS
THAT SWORN POLICE OFFICERS
ARE CURRENTLY DOING THAT
CIVILIANS CAN DO.
>> Reporter: THE DENVER
POLICE DEPARTMENT IS JOINING
SEVERAL OTHERS AROUND THE
COUNTRY HIRING CIVILIANS FOR
JOBS TRADITIONALLY HELD BY
SWORN POLICE OFFICERS,
INCLUDING CRIME SCENE
ANALYSIS, EVIDENCE GATHERING
AND LAB WORK.
>> PART OF IT IS OUR
RESPONSIBILITY TO BE GOOD
STEWARDS OF TAXPAYER DOLLARS
AND TO REALLY MAXIMIZE THE
USE OF OUR POLICE OFFICERS.
>> DEPARTMENTS WITH TIGHT
BUDGETS CAN SAVE A LOT OF
MONEY.
IF YOU HAVE A DETECTIVE WHO,
LET'S JUST THEORETICALLY IS
MAKING 90,000, AND YOU CAN
HIRE TWO PEOPLE TO FILL THAT
POSITION?
>> Reporter: CAN CIVILIANS,
EVEN IF HIGHLY TRAINED,
MATCH THE EXPERIENCE OF A
SEASONED DETECTIVE?
>> IT WILL DEPEND ON THE
TRAINING.
AND SOME OF IT IS DONE
THROUGH COLLEGES.
EDUCATIONAL PROGRAMS AND
THERE'S A LOT AVAILABLE.
>> Reporter: MARY DODGE
DIRECTS THE MASTERS OF
CRIMINAL JUSTICE PROGRAM AT
CU-DENVER.
SHE SAYS HIGHLY TRAINED
CIVILIANS CAN BRING A LOT TO
THE TABLE.
>> THEY CAN GO INTO THE
DEPARTMENT AND OFFER A GREAT
DEAL THAT A POLICE OFFICER
MAY HAVE NO TRAINING IN THAT
AREA.
>> Reporter: SHE SAYS THE
KEY TO MAKING IT WORK IS
COMBINING YEARS OF
EXPERIENCE DETECTIVES HAVE
WITH THE SKILLS TRAINED
CIVILIANS BRING.
>> THEY MAY MISS THE WHOLE
PICTURE.
SO IF YOU HAVE POLICE
OFFICERS STILL, SWORN
OFFICERS STILL IN YOUR CRIME
LAB, THEY CAN PUT THE PUZZLE
PIECES TOGETHER.
>> Reporter: AND THE CHIEF
SAYS HE ENVISIONS HIRING AN
ADDITIONAL 40 TO 50
CIVILIANS IN THE COMING
YEARS.
JENNA?
JENNA: INTERESTING IDEA.
ALICIA, THANK YOU.
JON: IT HAS HAPPENED BEFORE.
MUCH COPYCATS TRYING TO GET
ATTENTION.
ALSO GETTING THEIR
INSPIRATION FROM SCENES OF
MASS MURDER.
SO ARE THE NEWS MEDIA TO
BLAME WHEN THAT HAPPENS?
WE'LL GET INTO THAT WITH OUR
"NEWS WATCH" PANEL.
>>> A FRIGHTENING ORDEAL FOR
A TV REPORTER AND HIS CREW
KIDNAPPED IN SYRIA.
THEY ARE FREE NOW.
[ loud party sounds ]
HI,
I'M Ensure Clear...
Clear, HUH?
I'M NOT JUICE OR FANCY WATER.
I'VE GOTINE GRAMS OF PROTEIN.
THAT'S THREE TIMES MORE THAN ME!
[ Female Announcer ]
Ensure Clear.
NINE GRAMS PROTEIN. ZERO FAT.
IN BLUEBERRY/POMEGRANATE
AND PEACH.
JENNA: BRINGING YOU OUTLIVE
TO LOS ANGELES RIGHT NOW
WHERE WE HAVE LIVE SHOTS
RIGHT IN THE HEART OF L.A.
IN FACT.
THE LAND IS TELLING US THAT
THE BOMB SQUAD IS ON THE
SCENE WILSHIRE BOULEVARD
NEAR TEMPLE.
I'M NOT SURE BASED ON THE
HELICOPTER SHOT WHERE THE
HELICOPTER IS HEADED BASED
ON BUILDINGS IN THE AREA.
WE CAN TELL YOU THERE IS NO
EVACUATIONS ORDERED.
APPARENTLY THERE IS
PRECAUTION TAKING PLACE
RIGHT NOW.
THE ROBOT IS INVESTIGATING A
SUSPICIOUS DEVICE EITHER
ATTACHED OR CONNECTED TO A
CAR IN THE AREA.
NEAR THE TEMPLE LOCATION AT
WILSHIRE AND, AROUND
WILSHIRE AVENUE.
THE LOS ANGELES POLICE
DEPARTMENT ALSO TELLS US
THEY BELIEVE THE TEMPLE WAS
EVACUATED AS A PRECAUTION
OUT THERE.
THIS ALLING JUST AFTER 8:00
IN THE MORNING WEST COAST
TIME.
WE'LL KEEP YOU POSTED AS WE
HEAR MORE.
JON: RIGHT NOW THE DEADLY
SHOOTING RAMPAGE IN
CONNECTICUT SPARKING NEARLY
NONSTOP COVERAGE BY THE
MEDIA.
NEWS CREWS FROM AROUND THE
WORLD ARE CONVERGING ON THE
SCENE, GIVING THE KILLER A
LEVEL OF NOTE RIGHT THAT HE
CERTAINLY NEVER HAD IN LIFE.
AND NOW ALONG WITH GRIEF AND
SORROW FOR THE VICTIMS IT
THERE IS CONCERN ALL THIS
ATTENTION COULD ENCOURAGE
COPYCATS.
THERE'S ONE THING THAT FILM
CRITIC ROGER EBERT SAID IN
2003, COMMENTING ON THE NEWS
COVERAGE.
HE SAID, WHEN AN UNBALANCED
KID WALKS INTO A SCHOOL AND
SHORTS SHOOTING IT BECOMES A
MAJOR MEDIA EVENT.
CABLE NEWS DROPS ORDINARY
PROGRAMING AND GOES AROUND
THE CLOCK WITH IT.
THE MESSAGE IS CLEAR TO
OTHER DISTURBED KIDS, IF I
SHOOT UP MY SCHOOL, I CAN
BECOME FAMOUS.
THAT WAS THE CASE IN
COLUMBINE IN WHICH THE
KILLERS DREW SOME
INSPIRATION FROM THE BOMBING
IN OKLAHOMA CITY.
AND THE AMERICAN
PSYCHOLOGICAL ASSOCIATION
URGED NEWS OUTLETS NOT TO
PUBLICIZE THE WRITINGS AND
VIDEO OF THE VIRGINIA TECH
KILLER, FEARING IT WOULD
SPARK ANOTHER WAVE OF
COPYCATS.
TALK ABOUT IT WITH OUR "NEWS
WATCH" PANEL TODAY.
JIM PINKERTON IS
CONTRIBUTING EDITOR AND
WRITER FOR THE "AMERICAN
CONSERVATIVE" MAGAZINE.
ALAN COLMES IS HOST OF THE
"ALAN COLMES RADIO SHOW" AND
AUTHOR OF, THANK THE
LIBERALS FOR SAVING AMERICA.
JIM, YOU WORKED IN THE
REAGAN ADMINISTRATION I
BELIEVE, CORRECT?
>> YES, YES.
JON: RONALD REAGAN WAS SHOT
BY JOHN HINCKLEY, JR., A
MENTALLY UNSTABLE MAN WHO
THOUGHT HE WOULD WIN THE
ATTENTION OF JODIE FOSTER,
THE ACTRESS BY DOING THAT.
ARE THE MEDIA PART OF THE
PROBLEM HERE?
>> WELL, I MEAN I'M NOT AN
EXPERT BUT AS YOU MENTIONED
THE AMERICAN PSYCHOLOGICAL
ASSOCIATION, WHICH
PRESUMABLY ARE EXPERTS, THEY
SAID EXACTLY THIS.
THEY SAID THAT THIS IS A
MEDIA COPYCATTING SITUATION
AND THEY PLEADED TO NOT
PUBLICIZE THE SITUATION AT
LEAST OF THE KILLER IN
VIRGINIA TECH BACK IN 2007.
AND FRANKLY THAT ADVICE OR
THAT SUGGESTION WASN'T EVEN
HEEDED.
IT WAS SO BADLY HEEDED IN
FACT THAT THE MEDIA NOT ONLY
IDENTIFIED THE KILLER, THEY
IDENTIFIED THE WRONG KILLER.
THEY GOT THE KILLER'S
BROTHER.
I CAN REMEMBER BACK IN 1999,
IN THE COLUMBINE CASE, JON,
YOU AND I, ALL THREE OF US
WERE AT FOX AT THE TIME,
THERE WAS A LOT OF MOVEMENT
SAID DON'T MENTION THE NAMES
OF THE KILLERS.
YOU DIDN'T, SHOWED THEIR
PICTURES, NOT THEIR NAMES.
DON'T GIVE THEM CREDIT.
THAT WAS A GOOD POINT.
A LOT OF US TRIED TO ADHERE
TO THAT.
COMPLETELY LOST IN THIS CASE.
WE BETTER GET IT BACK.
JON: ALAN, WHAT IS YOUR
FEELING?
IS THE MEDIA A PART OF THIS
CRIMES?
>> IT IS HARD TO SAY.
JIM MAKES VERY GOOD POINTS
WHETHER PUBLICITY COULD
INSPIRE SOMEBODY TO DO SOME
HEINOUS ACT.
ON THE OTHER HAND WE LIVE IN
AN OPEN SOCIETY WITH A MEDIA
WHOSE JOB IT IS TO REPORT
THE NEWS.
I DON'T KNOW HOW THE MEDIA
CAN DO ITS JOB UNLESS THE
MEDIA IS GIVEN THE FREEDOM
TO EXPRESS ITSELF AND GIVE
THE FULL STORY.
I THINK THERE'S ALSO A
FASCINATION TO WANT TO KNOW
WHO ARE THE PEOPLE WHO
COMMIT THESE HEINOUS CRIMES.
WHAT ARE THEY LIKE?
WHAT INSPIRES THEM TO DO IT?
WHAT MOTIVATES THEM?
WHAT IS THE MIND LIKE.
IT GIVES US A ROUNDER
PICTURE.
BECAUSE WE KNOW WHO IT IS
AND WHAT THEY ARE THINKING
AND WHAT ISSUES MAY GO INTO
THEM COMMITTING THESE
TRAGEDIES, WE CAN THEN
ADDRESS THEM MORE FULLY.
SO I THINK THERE'S ANOTHER
SIDE TO THIS AS WELL THAT
WOULD INDICATE WE LIVE IN A
SOCIETY WHERE WE GET FULL
INFORMATION.
TRANSPARENCY IS VERY
IMPORTANT IN OUR SOCIETY.
I DON'T THINK WE WANT TO
AVOID THAT.
JON: EARLIER THIS YEAR I WAS
IN AURORA, COLORADO IN THE
AFTERMATH OF THE MOVIE
SHOOTING MASSACRE THERE, AND
THE GOVERNOR OF THAT STATE,
JOHN HICKENLOOPER AT THE
MEMORIAL SERVICE AFTERWARD
SAID SOMETHING THAT DREW THE
APPLAUSE OF THE CROWD.
I WANT TO PLAY THAT FOR YOU
NOW.
>> THE MOMENT THEY GOT NEWS,
THEY GOT THE CALL THAT CAME
THROUGH TO FROM DISPATCH
THEY WERE ON THE SCENE
WITHIN 2 1/2 MINUTES.
[APPLAUSE]
AND LITERALLY WITHIN SECONDS
THEY HAD APPREHENDED THE
SUSPECT.
[APPLAUSE]
AND I REFUSE TO SAY HIS NAME.
JON: OBVIOUSLY APPLAUSE FOR
THE POLICE AND THEIR HEROISM
THERE BUT THE BIGGEST
APPLAUSE LINE WHEN HE
REFUSED TO MENTION THE NAME
OF THE GUY WHO SHOT UP THAT
THEATER.
IS THAT, JIM, AN APPROACH
THAT MAYBE ALL OF US COULD
OR SHOULD TAKE IN THE
FUTURE?
>> YEAH.
AGAIN, I TEND TO AGREE.
I HAVE SYMPATHY FOR ALAN'S
POINT OF VIEW.
HE IS NOT WRONG IN WHAT HE
SAYS.
THIS IS TRANSPARENT SOCIETY
AND YOU DON'T WANT TO CRIMP
THE FREE PRESS.
I GUESS HOWEVER, UNLESS WE
WANT THIS TO HAPPEN ALL THE
TIME FOR THE REST OF OUR
LIVES WE BETTER START
THINKING OF SOMETHING AND
MULTIFACETED APPROACH WOULD
INCLUDE MENTAL HEALTH AND
ALL THAT GOES ALONG WITH
THAT.
NO REASON WHY WE COULDN'T
DIAGNOSE THE KILLER IN
CONNECTICUT EVEN AFTER HE IS
DEAD WITHOUT MENTIONING HIS
NAME.
WE HAVE TO LOOK AT VIOLENT
MOVIES.
VIOLENT VIDEOGAMES.
EVERYTHING WE DID TO KEEP
THE COUNTRY FROM FALLING
APART AND GOING TO PIECES IN
THE FIRST HALF OF THE 20th
CENTURY, WE UNDID IN THE
SECOND HALF OF THE 20th
CENTURY.
AND FOR EXAMPLE, LOOK AT
HAYES CODE IN THE MOVIES.
JON: THERE WAS A LOT OF
THIS SHOOTINGS,N THE EARLY
ALAN.
THE KILLER FIRST WAS 24.
THEN HE WAS 20 IT.
WAS THE OLDER BROTHER.
IT WAS THE YOUNGER BROTHER.
THE MOTHER WAS A TEACHER AT
THE SCHOOL.
THEN IT WASN'T.
IT GOES ON AND ON AND ON.
IS THAT WHAT HAPPENS IN THE
ERA OF FACEBOOK AND TWITTER?
>> I DON'T THINK IT IS A
MATTER OF FACEBOOK AND
TWITTER.
WHEN YOU HAVE A COMPLICATED
STORY AND NEW INFORMATION
COMING IN ALL THE TIME AND A
CHAOTIC SITUATION THIS
HAPPENS BECAUSE WE GET
INFORMATION THAT IS OFTEN
WRONG.
IN THIS CASE IT WAS BECAUSE
OF THE BROTHER OF THE KILLER
AND AN I.D. THAT WAS NOT
PARTICULAR TO THE KILLER.
AND, I DON'T KNOW THAT YOU
CAN BLAME IT ON SOCIAL MEDIA,
BUT AGAIN, THE MEDIA'S JOB
IS TO REPORT WHAT IT KNOWS
WHEN IT KNOWS IT AND DO
CORRECTIVE COURSES ALONG THE
WAY IF NECESSARY.
YOU DON'T WITHOLD
INFORMATION.
YOU GO WITH THE BEST
INFORMATION YOU HAVE.
IF YOU NEED TO DO A
CORRECTION, DO IT AS QUICKLY
AND EFFICIENTLY AS POSSIBLE.
JON: ALL RIGHT, ALAN COLMES,
JIM PINKERTON, GOOD
DISCUSSION AS ALWAYS.
THANK YOU BOTH.
>> THANK YOU.
JON: WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK
♪
CONSTIPATED?
YEAH.
MM.
SOME LAXATIVES LIKE Dulcolax
CAN CAUSE CRAMPS.
BUT Phillips' Caplets
DON'T.
THEY HAVE MAGNESIUM.
FOR EFFECTIVE RELIEF
OF OCCASIONAL CONSTIPATION.
THANKS.
[ Phillips' Lady ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE RHYTHM OF LIFE.
[ whistle blowing ]
WHERE DO YOU HEAR THAT BEAT?
CAMPBELL'S HEALTHY REQUEST SOUP
LETS YOU HEAR IT...
IN YOUR HEART.
[ basketball bouncing ]
HEART HEALTHY.
GREAT TASTE.
MMM...
[ Male Announcer ] SOUNDS GOOD.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.