BILL: WE ARE LIVE FROM NEW
TOWN CONNECTICUT AGAIN
TODAY.
WE'RE WAITING AN UPDATE FROM
THE POLICE ON THE
INVESTIGATION INTO THE
TRAGIC MASS SHOOTING.
THE MASSACRE IN THIS SMALL
TOWN.
AS THE COMMUNITY GRIEVES THE
DEATHS OF YOUNGEST AND MOST
INNOCENT.
FIRST OF 27 FUNERALS.
6-YEAR-OLD NOAH POSNER AND
6-YEAR-OLD JACK PINTO.
TO BE LAID TO REST 1:00
EASTERN TIME.
IT WILL BE AIFFICULT DAY.
I'M BILL HEMMER LIVE IN THIS
SPECIAL EDITION OF
"AMERICA'S NEWSROOM.".
MARTHA: GOOD MORNING BILL IN
CONNECTICUT.
I'M MARTHA MacCALLUM IN THE
NEW YORK STUDIO.
WE WATCHED LAST NIGHT AN
EMOTIONAL MEMORIAL SERVICE.
HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE PACKED
INTO THE AUDITORIUM AT
NEWTOWN HIGH SCHOOL.
PRESIDENT OBAMA MEETING
FIRST AND SEPARATELY WITH
THE FAMILIES OF THOSE WHO
WERE LOST.
IT MUST HAVE HAVE BEEN A
VERY DIFFICULT MEETING FOR
ALL INVOLVED IN THAT ROOM
LAST NIGHT.
WE SAW REPRESENTATIVES FROM
AIL FAITHS, MANY FAITHS
TAKING THE STAGE WITH A
MESSAGE OF HOPE AND REANCE.
>> I KNOW THAT NEWTOWN WILL
PREVAIL
IT IS A DEFINING MOMENT FOR
OUR TOWN BUT IT WILL NOT
DEFINE US.
>> I ASSURE YOU AT BEGINNING
OF WINTER I SEE THE
BEGINNING OF A SNOWFALL.
I WILL THINK OF THOSE 27
SOULS LOST JUST A FEW DAYS
AGO.
EACH TIME THE DAY GETS A
LITTLE LONGER I WILL THINK
AND DREAM OF THE LIVES THAT
MIGHT HAVE BEEN AND THE
LIVES THAT WERE SO FULL OF
GRACE.
BILL: PRESIDENT OBAMA THEN
TOOK THE STAGE
+++zq%
>> ALLISON.
GOD HAS CALLED THEM ALL
HOME.
FOR THOSE OF US WHO REMAIN,
LET US FIND THE STRENGTH TO
CARRY ON.
MAKE OUR COUNTRY WORTHY OF
THEIR MEMORY.
BILL: WE GET TO THE GRUESOME
DETAILS THAT OCCURRED ON
THIS SITE.
RIGHT AROUND THIS TIME ON
FRIDAY MORNING.
RICK LEVENTHAL MY COLLEAGUE
WITH ME THIS MORNING.
RICK, THE MOTHER NANCY WAS
SHOT FOUR TIMES IN THE HEAD
AND FOUND IN HER OWN HOME
STILL WEARING HER PAJAMAS
AND THAT'S WHERE WE BELIEVE
INVESTIGATORS WILL PICK UP
TODAY.
WHAT IS THE FOCUS NOW AS WE
START THIS DAY, RICK?
>> Reporter: BILL, THE
PRIMARY FOCUS FOR
INVESTIGATORS IS DETERMINING
WHAT MIGHT HAVE PROPELLED
THIS TROUBLED 20-YEAR-OLD TO
SHOOT HIS OWN MOTHER AND GUN
DOWN 26 OTHER INNOCENTS.
WE HAVE LEARNED, THROUGH
FAMILY AND FRIENDS THAT ADAM
LANZA HAD A FORM OF AUTISM
KNOWN AS ASPERGER'S.
THAT HE WAS TROUBLED.
THAT HE SPENT MOST OF HIS
TIME/8w INSIDE THE FAMILY HOME
AND THAT FRIDAY MORNING HE
WOKE UP, WENT TO HIS
MOTHER'S BEDROOM AND SHOT
HERSELF TIMES IN THE HEAD
BEFORE TAKING FOUR OF HER
WEAPONS, TAKING HER CAR, AND
DRIVING TO NEARBY SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WHERE HE
GUNNED DOWN SIX ADULTS AND
20 CHILDREN, ALL AGED 6 AND
7.
INVESTIGATORS ARE POURING
OVER A SMASHED COMPUTER
FOUND IN THE FAMILY HOME.
ALSO GOING THROUGH PHONE AND
CREDIT CARD RECORDS, LOOKING
FOR ANY AND ALL TYPES OF
CLUES THAT MIGHT LEAD TO
SOME ANSWERS HERE.
THERE MAY NOT BE ANY AS YOU
KNOW, BILL.
WE HAVE HEARD THAT THE
MOTHER, TOOK HER SON
SHOOTING.
THAT'S WHERE HE LEARNED HOW
TO SHOOT APPARENTLY, THE
WEAPONS THAT HER MOTHER
LEGALLY OWNED.
BUT BEYOND THAT
INVESTIGATORS HAVE A LOT OF
QUESTIONS STILL TO ANSWER.
BILL: IT IS EXTRAORDINARY TO
THINK AMOUNT OF DEVASTATION
CAUSED IN 10 MINUTES OR LESS
ACCORDING TO POLICE.
WE'VE BEEN HEARING FROM
POLICE THAT THIS COULD HAVE
BEEN EVEN WORSE THAN WE KNOW
IT TODAY.
HOW IS THAT POSSIBLE, RICK?
>> Reporter: WELL, HE WAS
CARRYING A VERY POWERFUL
BUSH MASTER.223.
IT IS AN AR-15 MILITARY
ASSAULT WEAPON.
IT IS THE MOST POWER GULL
GUN IN AMERICA AND CARRIES
30 ROUND CLIPS.
WENT THROUGH SEVERAL OF
THOSE.
HAD SEVERAL MORE CLIPS
UNUSED A COUPLE WITH OF
HANDGUNS AND UNSPENT BULLETS
AS POLICE WERE CLOSING IN.
HERE IS WHAT WE HEARD FROM
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE
YESTERDAY.
>> THE WEAPON UTILIZED MOST
OF THE TIME IN THIS HORRIFIC
CRIME WAS IDENTIFIED AS
BUSHMASTER.
AR-15 ASSAULT TYPE WEAPON.
IT HAD HIGH CAPACITY
MAGAZINES.
IN ADDITION TO THAT THE
SUBJECT HAD IN HIS
POSSESSION A GLOCK 10
MILLIMETER, A SIGG SAUER 9mm,
ALL WEAPONS HAD MULTIPLE
MAGAZINES AND ADDITIONAL
AMMUNITION.
>> Reporter: POLICE TOLD US
WHEN THEY WERE CLOSING IN,
WHEN THEY ARRIVED AT THE
SCHOOL AND WERE CLOSING IN
ON ADAM LANZA, THAT IS WHEN
HE USED ONE OF THE HANDGUNS
TO PUT A BULLET IN HIS OWN
HEAD, BILL.
BILL: THERE WERE HUNDREDS OF
ROUNDS OF AMMUNITION FOUND
INSIDE THE SCHOOL THAT WERE
LEFT, EITHER ON HIS PERSON
OR IN THAT CLASSROOM THAT
WENT UNUSED.
NOW, POLICE HAVE BEEN VERY
CAUTIOUS ON THESE PRESS
CONFERENCES.
A LOT OF INFORMATION FRANKLY
WENT OUT ON FRIDAY AND
SATURDAY THAT HAS NOT PROVEN
TO BE TRUE AND A LOT OF THAT
INFORMATION WAS PULLED BACK.
I THOUGHT THE INFORMATION
THEY GAVE OUT LAST NIGHT WAS
PRECIOUS AND FEW.
WHEN IT CAME TO FACTS.
DO WE BELIEVE THROUGH THE, I
GUESS YOU THERE THE BENEFIT
OF TIME THAT WE COULD LEARN
MORE FROM THIS BRIEFING
TODAY OR CAN WE ANSWER THAT,
RICK?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
IN ANY OF THESE KIND OF
INVESTIGATIONS THEY TRY TO
KEEP MANY OF THE FACTS TO
THEMSELVES AS THEY PROCESS
IT.
IT SLOWLY IS RELEASED.
ON FRIDAY THERE WAS A LOT OF
CONFUSION EVEN AMONG
INVESTIGATORS, INCLUDING
SOME FEDERAL SOURCES I WAS
SPEAKING WITH EXACTLY HOW
THESE EVENTS PLAYED OUT.
WHAT WE DO KNOW NOW THIS
YOUNG MAN WOKE UP, KILLED
HIS MOTHER, WENT TO THE
SCHOOL AND EXECUTED EVERYONE
ELSE BEFORE KILLING HIMSELF.
THE INVESTIGATORS MAY
RELEASE MORE INFORMATION
WHAT THEY FOUND IN THE
FAMILY HOME, WHAT THEY FOUND
IN THESE COMPUTER RECORDS,
WHETHER THIS YOUNG MAN MAY
HAVE LEFT BEHIND SOME SORT
OF MANIFESTO OR MADE ANY
THREATS ONLINE BEFORE
CARRYING OUT THIS ATTACK
WE'LL HOPEFULLY FIND OUT IN
THE NEXT HOUR OR SO, BILL.
BILL: I THINK YOU WOULD
AGREE WITH ME, PAUL VANCE
HAS BEEN AN OUTSTANDING LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICER AND
ADVOCATE FOR THE PEOPLE HERE
IN CONNECTICUT SINCE THIS
ORDEAL BEGAN.
WE WILL SEE HIM MOMENTARILY.
>> Reporter: ONE OTHER
+++)9N
BILL: WOM NEXT TO HIM.
IN THE SAME CONDITION.
THEY WOULD GET UP AND LEAVE
ANOTHER GROUP WOULD COME IN.
AND HAVE THE EXACT SAME
REACTION.
THAT GIVES YOU A SMALL, IDEA
MARTHA: IN THE TOWN THIS
MORNING.
AND THE PRESIDENT, MUCH THE
UNITED STATES, WE WATCHED
HIM LAST NIGHT.
HE VOWED TO TAKE ACTION AS
WELL.
HE POINTED OUT THAT AS
PRESIDENT HE HAS BEEN DOWN
THIS ROAD TOO MANY TIMES.
HE HAS GRIEVED WITH FAMILIES
OF FOUR DIFFERENT MASS
SHOOTINGS IN THIS COUNTRY.
MORE MUST BE DONE TO PROTECT
OUR CHILDREN.
>> CAN WE HONESTLY SAY WE'RE
DOING ENOUGH TO KEEP OUR
CHILDREN.
ALL OF THEM, SAFE FROM HARM?
WE'RE ALL TOGETHER THERE
LETTING THEM KNOW THAT
THEY'RE LOVED AND TEACHING
THEM TO LOVE IN RETURN?
CAN WE SAY THAT WE'RE TRULY
CHILDREN OF THIS COUNTRY THE
CHANCE THEY DESERVE TO LIVE
OUT THEIR LIVES IN=3 HAPPINESS
AND WITH PURPOSE?
I'VE BEEN REFLECTING ON THIS
THE LAST FEW DAYS AND IF
WE'RE HONEST WITH OURSELVES,
THE ANSWER'S NO.
WE'RE NOT DOING ENOUGH.
AND WE WILL HAVE TO CHANGE.
CAN WE DO, WHAT WILL WE DO
AS A NATION?
MARTHA: CONNECTICUT SENATOR
JOE LIEBERMAN IS CALL FOR
NATIONAL COMMISSION ON
VIOLENCE TO TAKE ON THIS
ISSUE AND GET OUR ARMS
AROUND IT IN A NONPOLITICAL
WAY IS WHAT SO MANY PEOPLE
ARE CALLING FOR.
HE JOINS US LATER THIS HOUR.
WE WILL SPEAK WITH HIM.
WE'VE GOT MUCH MORE AHEAD
THIS MORNING AND WE ARE
FOLLOWING SOME OTHER STORIES
THAT ARE HAPPENING OUT
+++;÷&
[ fishing rod casting line,
marching band playing ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THE RHYTHM OF LIFE.
[ whistle blowing ]
WHERE DO YOU HEAR THAT BEAT?
CAMPBELL'S HEALTHY REQUEST SOUP
LETS YOU HEAR IT...
IN YOUR HEART.
[ basketball bouncing ]
HEART HEALTHY.
GREAT TASTE.
MMM...
[ Male Announcer ] SOUNDS GOOD.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
TYOU WOULDN'T WANT YOUR
ADOCTOR DOING YOUR JOB,
HELLO....
SO WHY ARE YOU DOING HERS?
ONLY YOUR DOCTOR CAN DETERMINE
IF YOUR PERSISTENT HEARTBURN IS
ACTUALLY SOMETHING
MORE SERIOUS,
LIKE ACID REFLUX DISEASE.
OVER TIME, STOMACH
ACID CAN DAMAGE
THE LINING OF YOUR ESOPHAGUS.
FOR MANY, PRESCRIPTION NEXIUM
NOT ONLY PROVIDES
24-HOUR HEARTBURN RELIEF,
BUT CAN ALSO HELP HEAL
ACID-RELATED EROSIONS
IN THE LINING OF YOUR ESOPHAGUS.
THERE IS RISK OF BONE FRACTURE
AND LOW MAGNESIUM LEVELS.
SIDE EFFECTS MAY INCLUDE
HEADACHE, ABDOMINAL
PAIN AND DIARRHEA.
CALL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY IF
YOU HAVE PERSISTENT DIARRHEA.
OTHER SERIOUS STOMACH
CONDITIONS MAY EXIST.
DON'T TAKE NEXIUM IF
YOU TAKE CLOPIDOGREL.
LET YOUR DOCTOR DO HER JOB.
AND YOU DO YOURS.
ASK IF NEXIUM IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
IF YOU CAN'T AFFORD
YOUR MEDICATION,
ASTRAZENECA MAY BE ABLE TO HELP.
WHAT STARTS
WITH ADDING A FRIEND...
♪
...COULD END
WITH ADDING A CLOSE FRIEND.
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
FORMER FBI INVESTIGATOR AND
SENIOR VICE PRESIDENT OF THE
CONTROL RISK SECURITY
CONSULTING.
INTEREST MICHAEL STONE IS
PROFESSOR OF PSYCHIATRY AT
COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY.
BOTH OF YOU, GENTLEMEN,
THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME
HERE.
THESE ARE DIFFICULT
QUESTIONS, DR. TO TRY TO
FIGURE OUT WHAT I CAN TELL
YOU AFTER TALKING WITH
PEOPLE.
HE WOOS THE STANDOUT WHO WAS
SOCIALLY INCAPABLE OF
RELATING TO OTHER PEOPLE.
WHEN HE WOULD WALK DOWN THE
SIDEWALK HE WOULD STOP AND
STARE AT OTHER PEOPLE AND
STAIR AND STARE AND
PEOPLE LEFT AND WENT AWAY
FROM THEM.
WHY HE ACTED THAT WAY WAS
NOT WELL-KNOWN.
AND I THINK THE QUESTION,
DOCTOR, IS, WHERE'S THE
TRIGGER POINT TO TAKE AN
INDIVIDUAL WHO WAS
VULNERABLE AND WENT OWN
FRIDAY MORNING.
>> READ SOMETHING ABOUT THE
SITUATION BETWEEN HIM AND
HIS MOTHER.
EVERY DAY WE LEARNING IS A
LITTLE BIT KNEW.
HE WAS PERHAPS TO GO TO
COLLEGE.
AT SAME TIME, 20 YEARS OLD
AND WANTED TO FEEL THAT HE
COULD DO WITHOUT HER AND NOT
BEING A SISSY OR, PECULIAR
PERSON, THAT NEEDED
MOTHER-TO-BE WITH HIM OR
NEARBY, ALL THE TIME, SO I
THINK THERE IS SOMETHING IN
THAT CHEM CHRIS THAT MADE
HIM, REALLY BLOW AND GET
UNHINGED AND MOVE INTO A
STATE OF RAGE.
I MEAN, THE ONE THING THAT
STANDS OUT ABOUT MASS
MURDERER THEY ARE ALWAYS
FUELED BY WHITE HOT RAGE.
IT IS DIFFERENT FROM SERIAL
KILLERS, COOL, PLODDING,
STALKING, DRIVEN BY LUST.
MASS MURDERERS ARE
DIFFERENT.
SO SOMETHING TOUCHED OFF THE
RAGE AND I THINK IT HAD TO
DO WITH SOMETHING ODD IN THE
RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN THE
MOTHER AND HIM PARTICULARLY
AS HE IS IS, SHE IS TRYING
TO FIND PLACES AROUND THE
COUNTRY HE COULD GO TO
DIFFERENT COLLEGE.
BILL: YEAH.
BILL, I WANT YOU TO ADD TO
THAT, BUT I WANT YOU TO
CONSIDER THIS AS WELL.
THE PEOPLE WHO I TALK TO IN
SANDY HOOK, SAY THIS MOTHER
TRIED TO DO EVERYTHING
HUMANLY POSSIBLE SHE COULD
TO HELP HER OWN SON.
AND THIS WAS A LIFELONG
STRUGGLE FOR HER.
I THINK THERE WERE GOOD DAYS
AND FRANKLY THERE WERE BAD
DAYS.
FRIDAY WAS AN ABSOLUTE AWFUL
DAY.
HOW DO YOU ANSWER THAT
QUESTION?
>> WELL, BILL, YOU KNOW, YOU
CAN ONLY TO A SMALL DEGREE
TRY TO UNDERSTAND WHAT MAY
HAVE BEEN HAPPENING IN THAT
HOME AND, WITH HIM AND HIS
CONDITION AND HOW HIS MOTHER
WAS TRYING TO WORK WITH HIM.
WE'RE HEARING NOW SHE TOOK
HIM FOR OUTTO THE RANGE TO
USE, USE A WEAPON, YOU KNOW.
BUT ONE.
OTHER THINGS SHE WAS DOING
TO HELP HIM ALONG?
SHE WAS DEDICATING HER LIFE
TO HIM.
HOWEVER I THINK ONE OF THE
IMPORTANT THINGS THAT IS
COMING OUT OF ALL THIS, BILL,
THIS IS NUMBER ON DIFFERENT
LEVELS.
DISCUSSION ABOUT MENTAL
HEALTH.
IT IS DISCUSSION ABOUT
ISSUES IN OUR SOCIETY.
IT'S THE DISCUSSION AROUND
SCHOOL SAFETY AND SECURITY.
NONE OF THEM STAND ALONE.
IT BECOMES INTERMINGLE AND
COULD JOINED PROCESS.
SO TO THINK ANY ONE OF THEM
BY THEMSELVES WOULD HAVE
TAKEN CARE OF THIS, I THINK
WOULD BE NAIVE.
BILL: BILL, THANK YOU.
DOCTOR, THANKS SO YOU AS
WELL.
WE'RE AWAITING ON THE NEWS
CONFERENCE.
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANS FROM
THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
DEPARTMENT.
WE'LL DO BRIEFING.
HE HANDLED THEM BEGINNING
FRIDAY AFTERNOON.
THIS IS SOURCE OF GREAT
INFORMATION FOR US AS TO THE
INVESTIGATION.
AND AS TO THE WIFE.
GENTLEMEN, THANKS TO BOTH OF
YOU.
I CAN TELL NOW MOTIVE
ANNOUNCED YET.
NO WORD ON THAT.
NO WORD ON DIARIES OR
COMPUTER INFORMATION WILL
CERTAINLY IF FOUND AND
DISCOVERED, WHEN DECIPHERED
WILL BE CRITICAL COMPONENT
TO THE INVESTIGATION.
WE'RE WAITING THAT HERE IN
NEW TOWN.
GO BACK TO NEW YORK AND MORE
WITH MARTHA.
MARTHA: IT IS MONDAY MORNING
AND THE WHEELS OF NORMALCY
ARE TRYING TO START TO TURN
AGAIN IN WAY THEY CAN.
WE ARE OBSERVING MOMENTS
SILENCE AND SCHOOLCHILDREN
ARE GATHERING TO REMEMBER
THOSE LOST OVER THE WEEKEND
ON FRIDAY.
LET'S GO TO THE
NEW YORK STOCK EXCHANGE
WHERE THEY ARE, IN A MOMENT
OF SILENCE RIGHT NOW.
AS THEY REMEMBER THOSE LOST
JUST A COUPLE OF WEEKS
BEFORE CHRISTMAS.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[MOMENT OF SILENCE]
MARTHA: THIS MORNING AS THESE
FAMILIES BEGIN TO DEAL WITH THE
UNTHINKABLE, SOME ARE
REMEMBERING MAYOR PRECIOUS LOVED
ONES LIKE EMILIE PARKER.
HER FATHER WAS THE FIRST ONE TO
SPEAK OUT.
HE RECALLED THE LAST MOMENT HE
SAW HIS LITTLE GIRL.
>> SHE TOLD ME GOOD MORNING AND
ASKED HOW I WAS DOING AND I SAID
I WAS DOING WELL.
SHE SAID SHE LOVED ME AND I GAVE
HER A KISS AND I WAS OUT THE
DOOR.
MY DAUGHTER EMILIE WOULD BE ONE
OF THE FIRST ONES STANDING AND
GIVING HER LOVE AND SUPPORT TO
ALL THOSE VICTIMS BECAUSE THAT'S
THE TIME OF PERSON SHE IS.
MARTHA: HE REMEMBERS HER AS A
BRIGHT YOUNG GIRL WHO LOVED TO
DRAW.
AND SHE WAS TEACHING HER SISTERS
HOW TO READ.
THE NFL PAID TRIBUTE TO THE
SHOOTING VICTIMS.
THE NEW ENGLAND PATRIOTS ...
>> JOIN IN A MOMENT OF SILENT
REFLECT AS WE LIGHT A FLARE FOR
EACH OF THE VICTIMS.
MARTHA: 26 WHITE FLARES WERE
SENT INTO THE SKY.
ALSO THE NEW YORK GIANT PAID
THEIR RESPECT AS WELL.
VICTOR CRUISE RECALLED ONE OF
THE VICTIM'S FAMILIES AFTER
RECALLING THAT THEY WERE HUGE
FANS.
HE WROTE JACK PINTO ON ONE GLOVE
AND ON ONE OF HIS CLEATS HE
WOULD JACK PINTO MY HERO.
HIS FUNERAL IS ONE OF THE TWO
TODAY.
THEY ARE ONE OF THE FIR OF THE
FUNERALS THAT WILL TAKE UP A
LARGE PART OF THE COURSE OF THIS
WEEK.
HE SAYS HE WAS HUMBLED TO KNOW
THAT JACK WOULD BE BURIED
WEARING HIS CRUISE JERSEY.
BILL: MARTHA, WE JUST SAW
LIEUTENANT VAN LEAVE THE
FIREHOUSE BEHIND ME.
THE FIREHOUSE TO MY RIGHT --
THIS IS THE AREA THAT'S 100
YARDS DOWN THE ROAD FROM THE
SCHOOL.
THIS YOU WILL RECALL IS THE
PLACE WHERE SO MANY STUDENTS
WERE TOLD TO RUN OUT OF THE
BUILDING, GO THROUGH THE PARKING
LOT AND MEET UP WITH THE
FIREHOUSE.
MANY OF THE FAMILIES CAME HERE
AT 10:00 IN THE MORNING FRIDAY
MORNING TO FIND THEIR YOUNG
CHILDREN.
20 PARENTS WENT HOME WITHOUT A
CHILD THAT DAY.
THE FIREHOUSE IS WHERE A LOT OF
POLICE HAVE BEEN WORKING OUT OF.
THE STATE POLICE, TOO.
THERE ARE 26 TRIPLE TREES THAT
HAVE BEEN SET UP.
THIS IS ANOTHER MAKESHIFT
MEMORIAL THAT LATE LAST NIGHT IN
THE RAIN AND COLD IN SANDY HOOK,
CON.
THEY ALLOWED PEOPLE TO COME UP
THIS ROAD ABOUT A HALF MILE FROM
THE CENTER OF THE VILLAGE AND
PLACE THE WREATHS AND THE
BALLOONS AND DECORATE THE
CHRISTMAS TREES.
THEY ARE SO POIGNANT.
WHEN YOU SAW THE ORNAMENTS ON
THE TREES AND THE MEMENTOS
PEOPLE HAVE BROUGHT AND THEY
HAVE LEFT.
IT REALLY TUGS AT YOU.
IT'S A REMINDER OF A LOSS HOW
PEOPLE PEEL AN INTIMATE CONNECT
TO THE LIVES OF THE YOUNG, AGES
6 AND 7.
WE'LL SHARE A BIT MORE THAT IN
TOWN WITH YOU.
WE ARE AWAITING THIS NEWS
CONFERENCE.
WHEN IT BEGINS WE'LL HEAR FROM
PAUL VANCE AND WE'LL HEAR WHAT
HE HAS TO SAY.
THEY HAVE BEEN VERY CAREFUL
ABOUT THE INFORMATION THEY GIVE
OUT FROM THE VERY BEGINNING.
MARTHA: OBVIOUSLY MOTIVE IS ONE
OF THE THINGS PEOPLE ARE TRYING
TOO WHAT THEIR HEADS AROUND.
WE ARE HEARING MORE WITH ADAM
LANZA.
HIS PARENTS DIVORCED.
HIS FAMILY MOVED TO IN THE *.
H -- MOVED TONEWTOWN.
FROM WHAT WE KNOW ABOUT HIM.
SOCIAL INTERACROSS WAS DIFFICULT
FOR THIS BOY.
HE WAS KNOWN IN HIGH SCHOOL TO
CARRY AROUND A BLACK BRIEFCASE
INSTEAD OF A BACKPACK AND HE
NEVER WANTED TO LET THAT
BRIEFCASE GO.
WE KNOW THAT HE WAS ALSO HAD
LOOKED AT ENGINEERING SCHOOLS
WITH HIS MOTHER.
THAT RAISES QUESTIONS ABOUT HOW
HE FELT ABOUT THAT TRANSITION.
WHETHER HE WAS OPEN TO THAT
TRANSITION IN HIS LIFE.
THESE ARE THE THINGS PEOPLE ARE
PORING OVER AS THEY TRY TO
FIGURE OUT THE WHY, WHICH IS THE
HUGE QUESTION HERE.
WE'LL SEE WHAT WE LEARN FROM
THIS NEWS CONFERENCE AS IT GETS
UNDERWAY IN A COUPLE MINUTES.
BILL: WE ARE JUST GETTING WORD
OF THIS AND WE ARE WORKING
THROUGH IT.
WE ARE NOT QUITE SURE WHAT'S
HAPPENING.
THE SCHOOLS IN THIS AREA ARE
CLOSED.
BUT THE TOWN OF RIDGEFIELD ABOUT
30 MINUTES AWAY WHICH IS WEST OF
HERE A COUPLE MILES.
APPARENTLY THE SCHOOLS ARE UNDER
LOCKDOWN BECAUSE OF A SUSPICIOUS
PERSON AT THE NEARBY TRAIN
STATION.
WE DON'T KNOW IF THIS WILL
AMOUNT TO ANYTHING, IT MAY BE A
SENSE OF PARANOIA.
BUT THIS GOES ALONG WITH WHAT WE
WERE TOLD LAST NIGHT AT THE
CATHOLIC CHURCH INCH TOWN.
THEY HAD 800 PEOPLE GATHER FEAR
MEMORIAL SERVICE.
THERE WAS A THREAT THAT CAME OUT
AND THE PASTOR CAME OUT AND HAD
TO HAVE EVERYBODY MOVE OUT OF
THE CHURCH.
THERE WAS A STRONG WARNING THAT
WENT OUT FROM THE POLICE.
IF YOU ARE MAKING ANONYMOUS
THREATS ONLINE THROUGH SOCIAL
MEDIA YOU WILL BE PROSECUTED AND
HELD ACCOUNTABLE.
EXPECT TO HEAR SOMETHING SIMILAR
FROM THE LIEUTENANT HERE IN A
MATTER OF MOMENT.
>> GOOD MORNING.
WHAT WE WOULD LIKE TO DO I
PROVIDE SOME DETAILS, SOME
UPDATES.
I WOULD LIKE TO OPEN UP, THE
LIEUTENANT IS GOING TO OPEN UP
WITH A MESSAGE FROM THE
SUPERINTENDENT OF SCHOOLS.
>> THE HEALING IS STILL GOING
ON.
SCHOOLS ARE WORKING CLOSELY WITH
ALL THE FACULTY, STUDENTS AND
PARENT TO TRY TO BE RESPECTFUL
AND TRY TO RESUME WHAT NORMALCY
WE CAN AFTER A TRAGEDY SUCH AS
THIS.
ALL THE FACULTY IS MEETING TODAY
AT THE NEWTOWN HIGH SCHOOL TO
PLAN FURTHER ON HOW TO ATRETS
NEEDS OF THE STUDENT AND FACULTY
INVOLVED IN THIS HORRENDOUS
TRAGEDY.
THERE WILL BE NO SCHOOL TODAY.
THE PLAN IS TO TRY TO RESUME
NORMALCY FOR SCHOOL CLASSES
TOMORROW EXCEPT FOR THOSE
MEMBERS AT THE SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL.
THEY WILL BE EXCUSED UNTIL
FURTHER NOTICE.
THEY ARE DEVELOPING PLANS HOW TO
BEST HANDLE THAT AS WE SPEAK.
>> WE ARE CONTINUING THE LINE OF
COMMUNICATION WITH THE TROOPERS
AND OFFICERS ASSIGNED TO THE
FAMILIES AS WE BEGIN THE
SERVICES.
ADDITIONAL TROOPERS HAVE BEEN
ASSIGNED TO WORK EACH ONE OF THE
FUNERAL SERVICES WITH LOCAL
OFFICERS AND OTHER POLICE
PARTNERS.
WE ARE ASKING THE MEDIA AGAIN AT
THE FAMILY'S REQUEST TO RESPECT
THEIR PRIVACY AS THEY GO THROUGH
THIS EXTREMELY DIFFICULT TIME.
AS I STATED, MAJOR CRIME
DETECTIVES HAVE BEEN WORKING 24
HOURS A DAY SINCE THE TRAGEDY
OCCURRED AND WILL CONTINUE TO DO
SO INDEFINITELY AS THEY CONTINUE
TO ANSWER QUESTIONS SURROUNDING
THIS TRAGEDY AND HOW AND WHY IT
OCCURRED.
THERE ARE MANY, MANY WITNESSES
THAT NEED TO BE INTERVIEWED.
WE'LL NOT STOP UNTIL WE
INTERVIEWED EVERY LAST ONE OF
THEM.
WE ARE HOLDING BOTH CRIME
SCENES, THE SCHOOL AND THE
SECONDARY CRIME SCENE
INDEFINITELY.
WE SEIZED IT UNDER SEARCH
WARRANTS AND WE'LL HOLD THOSE
LOCATIONS UNTIL WE COMPLETED OUR
WORK.
SO NOT TO READ ANYTHING INTO
THAT.
IT'S COMMON PRACTICE TO HOLD
ONTO THE CRIME SCENE LONG IT'S
NEEDED FOR INVESTIGATION
PURPOSES.
WE HAVE BEGUN ANALYZING THE
EVIDENCE.
THE WEAPONRY.
EVERY SINGLE FACET OF THE
WEAPONS WILL BE ANALYZED.
EVERY SINGLE ROUND OF AMMUNITION
WILL BE LOOKED AT FOR PHYSICAL
EVIDENCE.
I ALLUDED TO THE VOLUME OF ROUND
THAT WERE SEIZED AND RECOVERED.
EACH SINGULAR ROUND WILL BE
EXAMINED.
IT GIVES YOU AN IDEA OF THE
PAINSTAKING LENGTH OF THAT
PROCESS.
WE'LL ANALYZE EVERY SINGLE
PIECE.
I CANNOT DETAIL ANY EVIDENCE OR
WHAT THAT EVIDENCE IS FOR
PURPOSE CONSUMPTION.
I WANT TO RESTATE AGAIN AND
THANK YOU FOR HELPING US IN
THIS, BUT ANY THREATS, ANY
INFORMATION INTENDED TO MISLEED
INVESTIGATORS IN THIS CASE WILL
BE COMPLETELY AND THOROUGHLY
INVESTIGATED AND PROSECUTED IF
ANYONE ATTEMPTS TO THREATEN OR
MISLEED THIS INVESTIGATION.
-- MISLEAD THIS INVESTIGATION.
STATE POLICE DECKS HAVE BEEN
ASSIGNED TO INVESTIGATE THOSE.
THE CRISIS TEAMS ARE STILL IN
PLACE.
I WHAT TO GIVE YOU THAT PHONE
NUMBER AGAIN.
THERE ARE MANY PEOPLE IN TOWN
AND THIS PHONE LINE IS OPEN TO
ANYONE WHO NEEDS TO DISCUSS
ANYTHING OR NEEDS SUPPORT FROM
PROFESSIONALS.
THEY ARE STAFFING THIS LINE FROM
THE HOSPITAL.
203-2O 70-4283.
-- 270-4283.
THERE ARE CERTAIN AREAS WE
CANNOT GO DOWN AT THIS POINT IN
TIME.
QUESTIOTHE LOCAL POLICE DEPARTMS
HANDLING THAT SITUATION.
THERE IS A ROOFORT SUSPICIOUS
PERSON WHO MAY BE ARMED.
WE ARE NOT SURE WHAT THE
SITUATION IS.
WE SENT APPROPRIATE PERSONNEL TO
ASSIST BUT RICHFIELD IS HANDLING
THAT SITUATION.
THERE ARE NO UPDAYS.
THE SCHOOLS ARE SAFE WITH THE
RIDGEFIELD POLICE DEPARTMENT.
THEY ARE HANDLING THAT.
>> YOU MENTION YOU ARE
INTERVIEWING WITNESSES, THAT
INCLUDES CHILDREN.
>> I DON'T WANT TO GET INTO
DETAILS.
IT'S A TENDER ISSUE.
ANY INTERVIEW WITH CHILDREN WILL
BE DONE WITH PARENT AND
PROFESSIONALS AND PARENTS AS
APPROPRIATE.
THE INVESTIGATORS WILL DETERMINE
HOW, WHEN, WHERE AND WHY.
WE'LL HANDLE THAT HE CAN REAL
LIDDELL CATTILY WHEN THE TYPE
ARISES.
>> DID ANY MEDICAL OR MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS COME
FORWARD TO SAY IF THEY ARE
TREATING ADAM LANZA?
>> WE WOULD ENCOURAGE ANYONE
WITH INFORMATION TO COME FORWARD
WHO COULD ASSIST US IN THIS
INVESTIGATION.
WHEN I TALKED ABOUT THE WEAPONRY
INVOLVED, THE SAME THING HOLD
TRUE WITH THE SUSPECT.
WE'LL GO BACK TO THE DATE OF
BIRTH AND CONTINUE ON THROUGH.
WE'LL AND EVERY SINGLE QUESTION
DETERMINING ANY MEDICAL
CONDITION OR ANY ISSUE THEY MAY
HAVE BEEN INVOLVED IN.
I'M NOT AT LIBERTY TO DISCUSS
CONTENT OR ANY INFORMATION SO
FAR UNCOVERED.
BUT SUFFICE IT TO SAY, WE'LL
COVER EVERY SINGLE FACET.
>> THERE ARE REPORTS THERE WERE
CONCERNS WILL ADAM LANZA --
>> THERE WAS NO PREVIOUS CONTACT
OR CONCERNS PRIOR TO THIS TRAGIC
EVENT.
>> IS THERE MORE DETAIL HOW HE
GOT IN THE SCHOOL AND WHAT HE
DID WON INSIDE.
>> I CAN'T DO THAT.
IT'S TOO DIFFICULT TO DISCUSS.
I CAN TELL YOU AS I HAVE BEEN
TELLING YOU, THE SUSPECT FORCED
HIS WAY INTO THE SCHOOL BEFORE
AND AS HE BEGAN TO TAKE HUMAN
LIFE THEREIN, I SIMPLY DON'T
WANT TO AND IT'S NOT APPROPRIATE
FOR TO US GO ANY FURTHER WITH
THAT.
>> [INAUDIBLE] MORE
INFORMATION -- FIREARM.
>> THE QUESTION IS ARE WE
CHECKING.
YES, WERE CHECK CAN THE
WEAPONRY.
ATF AND OTHER STATE AGENCIES ARE
SEARCH EVERY RECORD, SEARCHING
EVERYTHING WE POSSIBLY CAN
UNCOVER.
IF ANYBODY HAD CONTACT WITH THE
SUSPECT IN ANY LOCATION WE WANT
TO TALK TO THEM IF WE HAVEN'T
REACHED THEM YET.
>> HAS PROGRESS BEEN MADE TRYING
TO GET INFORMATION FROM THE
COMPUTERS.
>> OUR COMPUTER CRIMES UNIT WORK
AS PART OF THE FORENSIC
LABORATORY ARE WORKING NONSTOP
EXAMINING ANY INFORMATION THAT
WAS SEIZED.
ALL THE ELECTRONIC EVIDENCE WILL
BE ANALYZED AND WE'LL DISSECT
IT.
>> DID ADAM DESTROY EVIDENCE AT
HIS HOME?
>> I CAN'T DISCUSS THE EVIDENCE.
>> IS THERE A SECOND SURVIVOR?
>> THERE ARE TWO ADULT THAT WERE
INJURED IN THE SCHOOL THAT
SUFFERED GUNSHOT WOUNDS AND ARE
RECOVERING.
I DON'T HAVE ANY INFORMATION
ABOUT WHAT HE WAS CARRYING ON
HIS PERSON.
>> THERE IS NO INFORMATION ON
HOW HE GOT HIS BROTHER'S I.D.?
>> IS THERE A SURVEILLANCE
SYSTEM INSIDE THAT SCHOOL?
>> I DON'T HAVE THAT
INFORMATION.
>> [INAUDIBLE]
>> THAT WILL AND TOWN DECISION
WITH TOWN LEADERS.
AGAIN WE ARE POSSESSING THAT
SCHOOL.
WE ARE HOLDING THAT SCHOOL AS A
CRIME SCENE AND I CAN'T TELL
WHAT YOU THAT MEANS.
I DON'T KNOW HOW LONG THAT WILL
BE.
I'M SUSPECTING MONTHS.
AT THAT TIME IT'S UP TO THE TOWN
OFFICIALS TO DETERMINE WHAT MANY
APPROPRIATE WITH THAT FACILITY.
>> CAN YOU TALK ABOUT HOW THE
TWO SURVIVORS ARE HELPING?
>> WE PROVIDED THE SURVIVORS
WITH THE SAME CON DIET AS WE
RIDED ALL THE VICTIMS IN THIS
CASE.
LAW ENFORCEMENT ESCORT, IF YOU
WILL.
OUR INVESTIGATORS WILL SPEAK
WITH THEM WHEN IT'S MEDICALLY
APPROPRIATE AND CERTAINLY THEY
WILL SAID A GREAT DEAL OF LIGHT
ON THE FACTS AND CIRCUMSTANCE OF
THIS TRAGIC INVESTIGATION WE ARE
UNDERTAKING.
BILL: WE ARE TOLD TO RESPECT THE
PRIVACY OF THE FAMILIES THERE.
SOMETHING WE'LL WELL RESPECT
HERE IN SANDY HOOK.
WHAT I EERIE ABOUT THIS TIME ON
THE CLOCK.
IT'S 9:42 SHAIS A.M.
IT WAS 72 HOURS AT THIS MOMENT
DOWN THIS STREET WHERE THE
MASSACRE TOOK PLACE.
THERE IS MORE NEWS NOW.
FOR THAT BACK TO MARTHA IN NEW
YORK.
MARTHA: WE WANT TO GET THIS
INFORMATION TO YOU.
BREAKING NEWS IN THE POLITICAL
WORLD AS WAS MUCH ANTICIPATED.
REPRESENTATIVE TIM SCOTT WILL
REPLACE THE OUTGOING SENATOR JIM
DEMINT TO LEAD THE HERITAGE
FOUNDATION.
HE WILL MOVE ON TO DO THAT.
REPRESENTATIVE PARTICULAR SCOTT
HAS BEEN CHOSEN BY GOVERNOR
NIKKI HALEY TO TAKE HIS PLACE.
HE WILL BECOME A SENATOR.
BILL: IN THE AFTERMATH OF WHAT
HAPPENED HERE IN NEWTOWN.
CALLS FOR A FEDERAL COMMISSION
ON VIOLENCE.
THERE ARE SO MANY AREAS OF FOCUS
HERE.
SENATOR JOE LIEBERMAN IS LEADING
THAT CHARGE.
HE'S MY GUEST AS WE ALL TRY AND
MAKE SENSE OF THIS.
but with ADVAIR,
I'm breathing better.
So now I can be in
the scene.
ADVAIR is
clinically proven to help
significantly improve
lung function.
Unlike most COPD medications,
ADVAIR contains both an
anti-inflammatory
and a
long-acting bronchodilator
working together to help improve
your lung function all day.
ADVAIR won't
replace fast-acting inhalers
for sudden symptoms
and should not be used more
than twice a day.
People with
COPD taking ADVAIR
may have a higher chance
of pneumonia.
ADVAIR may increase your
risk of osteoporosis
and some eye problems.
Tell your doctor
if you have a heart condition
or high blood pressure before
taking ADVAIR.
If you're still
having difficulty breathing,
ask your doctor if including
ADVAIR could help
improve your lung function.
Get your
first full
prescription
free
and save
on refills
at
ADVAIRcopd.com.
YOU HAVE A PLAN?
FIRST WE'RE GONNA
CHECK OUR BAGS FOR FREE,
THANKS
TO OUR EXPLORER CARD.
THEN, THE UNITED CLUB.
MY MOTR
WAS SO WRONG ABOUT YOU.
NEXT,
WE GET PRIORY BOARDING
ON OUR FLIGHT
I BOOKED WITH MILES.
ALL BECAUSE OF THE CARD.
AND ME.
OKAY, WHAT'S THE PLAN?
PLAN?
MM-HMM.
WE'RE ON VACATION.
THERE IS NO PLAN.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ] THE UNITED
MILEAGEPLUS EXPLORER CARD.
THE MILEAGE CARD
WITH SPECI PERKS ON UNITED.
GET IT AND YOU'RE IN.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT STARTED LONG AGO.
THE JOY OF GIVING SOMETHING
EVERYTHING YOU'VE GOT.
IT TAKES PASSION.
AND IT'S NOT LETTING UP
ANYTIME SOON.
AT UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company,
WE UNDERSTAND THAT COMMITMENT.
AND ALWAYS HAVE.
SO DOES AARP,
AN ORGANIZATION
SERVING THE NEEDS
OF AMERICANS 50 AND OVER
FOR GENERATIONS.
SO IT'S NO SURPRISE
MILLIONS HAVE CHOSEN
AN AARP Medicare Supplement
Insurance Plan,
INSURED BY UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company.
LIKE ALL STANDARDIZED
MEDICARE SUPPLEMENT PLANS,
THEY HELP COVER
SOME OF THE EXPENSES
MEDICARE DOESN'T PAY.
AND SAVE YOU UP TO THOUSANDS
IN OUT-OF-POCKET COSTS.
TO FIND OUT MORE,
REQUEST YOUR
FREE DECISION GUIDE.
CALL OR GO ONLINE TODAY.
AFTER ALL,
WHEN YOU'RE GOING THE DISTANCE,
IT'S NICE TO HAVE
THE EXPERIENCE AND COMMITMENT
TO GO ALONG WITH YOU.
KEEP DREAMING. KEEP DOING.
GO LONG.
BILL: POLICE SAYING A MOMENT AGO
THE SCHOOL WILL BE A CRIME SCENE
UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE.
EVERYTHING HAS BEEN BLOCKED OFF
AND FOR GOOD REASON.
A COMMUNITY AND FRANKLY THE
COUNTRY NUMB WITH GRIEF AS WE
REMEMBER THE VICTIMS OF ONE OF
THE WORST MASS MURDERS IN
HISTORY.
MY NEXT GUEST KNOWS THE STATE
VERY WELL.
AMID THE SORROW HE'S CALLING FOR
A NATIONAL COMMISSION ON
VIOLENCE TO PREVENT THIS FROM
HAPPENING AGAIN.
JOE LIEBERMAN, INDEPENDENT
SENATOR, GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
WHETHER IT'S VIOLENT MOVIES,
VIDEO GAMES, MENTAL HEALTH, THE
RELATIONSHIP OF A PAINT AND A
CHILD AND A CHILD WITH A PARENT,
YOU WERE TALKING THIS WEEKEND
ABOUT A WAY TO GET AT THIS.
HOW DO YOU DO THAT?
>> AS PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID LAST
NIGHT IN A MOVING AND ELOQUENT
AND IMPORTANT SPEECH HERE IN
CONNECTICUT.
THIS IS COMPLICATED.
BY THE FACT THAT IT'S
COMPLICATED DOESN'T MEAN WE CAN
TURN AWAY FROM IT OR LET IT GET
STOPPED IN LEGISLATIVE GRIDLOCK
BECAUSE THESE TRAGEDIES CONTINUE
TO OCCUR.
THEY MEAN AS A SOCIETY WE ARE
FAILING TO PROTECT OURSELVES.
IN THE NEWTOWN CASE FAILING TO
DO THE MOST ELEMENTAL
RESPONSIBILITY OF A CIVIL
SOCIETY AND THAT IS PROTECT OUR
CHILDREN.
I'M TALKING ABOUT A NATIONAL
COMMISSION ON MASS VIOLENCE.
I DON'T WANT US TO LEAVE THE
HEARTACHE AND ANGER THAT WE FEEL
AT WHAT HAPPENED IN NEWTOWN
HERE.
I WANT TO ENGENDER -- I THINK
THE PRESIDENT DOES TOO, A
NATIONAL CONVERSATION IN WHICH
WE ASK OURSELVES HOW CAN WE AS
BEST PASS POSSIBLE STOP THIS
FROM HAPPENING.
THERE IS A PATTERN HERE.
MOST OF THESE HORRIFIC ACTS OF
MASS VIOLENCE ARE COMMITTED BY
YOUNG MEN WHO IN HIND SIDE
EVERYBODY SAYS WERE -- HINDSIGHT
THEY WERE TROUBLED.
THEY HAVE BEEN INVOLVED WITH
VIOLENT ENTERTAINMENT CULTURE,
THEN THEY GET GUNS.
WE HAVE TO BRING EVERYBODY TO
THE TABLE INCLUDING THE GUN
RIGHTS AND THE ENTERTAINMENT
INDUSTRY.
THIS OUR NATIONAL PROBLEM AND WE
HAVE THE ABILITY TO AT LEAST
MAKE SURE THAT FEWER CHILDREN,
HOPEFULLY NEVER AGAIN CHILDREN
LIKE THIS WILL BE KILLED IN ONE
OF THESE EVENTS.
BILL: IT'S DIFFICULT HERE AND
FULLY RESPECTING YOUR RESPONSE.
FROM THE OUTSIDE LOOKING IN.
PEOPLE WONDER WHAT CAN BE DONE.
WHERE CAN A COVERING LIKE THAT
LEAD?
I DON'T KNOW IF THERE IS A CLEAR
ANSWER FOR THAT RIGHT NOW.
>> I THOUGHT WHAT THE PRESIDENT
SAID LOUISIANA NIGHT THE FACT
THAT IT'S COMPLICATED DOESN'T
MEAN WHEN CAN'T DO ANYTHING
ABOUT IT.
IF WE CAN SAVE THE LIFE OF ONE
CHILD IN THE COUNTRY THEN IT'S
WORTH IT.
BUT PART OF THIS ABOUT STABBING
A COMMISSION IS TO MAKE SURE
THAT ALL THE HE MOAGS WE FEEL
NOW DON'T JUST GO AWAY OVER A
PERIOD OF WEEK OR MONTHS.
BUT THERE ARE THING WE CAN DO.
THERE ARE THING WE CAN SAY TO
PEOPLE, PARENT, FRIEND,
TEACHERS.
WHEN YOU SEE A CHILD, A YOUNG
MAN PARTICULARLY SHOWING SIGNS
OF BEING IN TROUBLE, LET'S FIND
OUT HOW TO MAKE SURE IT GET THE
BEST MENTAL HEALTH.
THE ENTERTAINMENT CULTURE, I
THINK THEY HAVE GOT TO ACCEPT
SOME RESPONSIBILITY.
OBVIOUSLY NOT EVERY CHILD OR
YOUNG MAN WHO PLAYS A VIOLENT
VIDEO GAME IS GOING TO BECOME A
SHOOTER.
BUT THERE ARE PEOPLE OUT THERE
IN MY OPINION MADE MORE VIOLENT
BY THESE GAMES.
>>
>> .
♪ THE WEATHER OUTSIDE
IS FRIGHTFUL ♪
♪ BUT THE FIRE IS
SO DELIGHTFUL ♪
NOTHING MELTS AWAY THE COLD
LIKE A HOT, DELICIOUS BOWL
OF CHICKEN NOODLE SOUP
FROM CAMPBELL'S.
♪ LET IT SNOW, LET IT SNOW
MARTHA: WE'LL BE CONTINUING TO
GO BACK TO NEWTOWN THROUGHOUT
THE MORNING.
BUT WE WANT TO BRING YOU A BIT
OF NEWS IN THE HEADLINES.
EGYPT POSSIBLY ON THE BRINK OF A
NEW ROUND OF VIOLENCE AFTER
ISLAMIST LEADERS CLAIM THEY HAVE
A MAJORITY OF THE VOTES IN THE
FIRST ROUND OF THIS EVERY EVEN
DUMB ON THIS HIGHLY
CONTROVERSIAL DRAFT OF THE
CONSTITUTION THAT WOULD GIVE THE
LEADER MANY POWERS MANY BELIEVE
HE SHOULD NOT HAVE.
WHAT HAS BEEN THE REACTION TO
THE FIRST RESULT?
>> EVENINGS ARE HIGH AFTER THE
FIRST ROUND OF VOTING ON THE
DRAFT CONSTITUTION HERE IN CAIRO
AND ELSEWHERE.
THE RESULT WERE CLOSER THAN
EXPECTED.
THE TURNOUT LOWER THAN USUAL
ACCORDING TO OPPOSITION FIGURES.
THE VOTE WAS MARRED BY
IRREGULARITIES.
THE OPPOSITION LEADERS ARE
CALLING FOR MORE PROTESTS AT THE
PRESIDENTIAL PALACE, TAHRIR
SQUARE AND THE STREET LEADING UP
TO THE U.S. EMBASSY.
MARTHA: HOW DO THEY SEE THIS
PLAYING OUT?
>> THIS IS THE FIRST ROUND OF
VOTING.
THE SECOND ROUND IS SATURDAY.
CRITICS SAY IT'S ISLAMISTS.
THE DEFENDERS SAY IT'S CRITICAL.
THESE RESULT SHOULD FURTHER
EXTEND THE DIVIDE NEAR THIS
COUNTRY.
KEEP ALIVE THE VIOLENCE AND THE
CHALLENGE OF RECOVERY.
MARTHA: THANK YOU VERY MUCH,
GREGG PALKOT.
BILL AROUND ONE OTHER THING WE
LEARNED TODAY IS THERE ARE MANY
WITNESSES STILL TO BE
QUESTIONED.
MANY OF THEM MAY INCLUDE SMALL
YOUNG CHILDREN.
BUT IT WILL BE DONE IN THE
FULLEST AMOUNT OF RESPECT WITH
PEOPLE ON HAND TO HELP POLICE DO
THAT.
THE CRIME SCENE COULD BE SEALED
FOR MONTHS.
THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL 100 YARD
DOWN THE ROAD MAY NEVER OPEN
AGAIN.
PRESIDENT OBAMA TRYING TO HEAL
THE NATION.
AND A POIGNANT SALUTE TO THE
LIVES THAT WILL TRY TO FIND A
WAY TO MOVE FORWARD.
AS WE MOVE FORWARD AS WELL.
ANOTHER HOWEVER OUR SPECIAL
EDITION COVERAGE HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
CASH REWAR,
I LOVE 'EM EVEN MORE.
I EARN 1% CASH BACK EVERYWHERE,
EVERTIME.
2% ON GROCERIES.
3% ON GAS.
AUTOMATICALLY.
NO HOOPS TO JUMP THROUGH.
THAT'S 1% BACK ON...
[ toy robot sounds ]
2% ON PUMPN PIE.
AND APPLE.
3% BACK ON 4 TRIPS
TO THE AIRPORT.
IT'S AS EASY AS..
-[ man ] 1...
-[ woman ] 2...
[ woman ] 3.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CARD.
APPLY ONLINE OR AT
A BANK OF AMERICA NEAR YOU.
MARTHA: A SOMBER REMINDER OF
FRIDAY'S TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THE PARENT OF TWO YOUNG CHILDREN
PREPARE TO LAY THEM TO REST
TODAY.
IT'S A CRIME THAT POLICE ARE
STILL TRYING TO PIECE TOGETHER
MORE THAN 72 HOUR AFTER THE
FIRST SHOT WAS FIRED.
>> STATE POLICE MAJOR CRIME
DETECTIVES HAVE BEEN WORKING 24
HOURS A DAY SEASON THIS TRAGEDY
OCCURRED AND WILL CONTINUE TO DO
SO INDEFINITELY AS THEY CONTINUE
TO ANSWER QUESTIONS SURROUNDING
THIS TRAGEDY AND HOW AND WHY IT
OCCURRED.
THEY ARE CONTINUING TO INTERVIEW
WITNESSED.
THERE ARE MANY, MANY WITNESSES
THAT NEED TO BE INTERVIEWED.
WE'LL NOT STOP UNTIL WE
INTERVIEWED EVERY LAST ONE OF
THEM.
WE HAVE GUN PROCESSION AND
ANALYZING THE EVIDENCE.
AS I STATED YESTERDAY.
THE WEAPONRY.
EVERY SINGLE FACET OF THE WEAPON
WILL BE ANALYZED.
EVERY SINGLE ROUND OF AMMUNITION
WILL BE LOOKED AT AND EXAMINED
FOR PHYSICAL EVIDENCE.
MARTHA: SO MUCH WORK TO BE DONE
SUCH HARD WORK LIES AHEAD OF
THEM.
THE WITNESSES, SO MANY OF THEM
ARE YOUNG CHILDREN.
WELCOME BACK TO A BRAND-NEW HOUR
OF THIS SPECIAL EDITION.
I'M MARTHA MACCALLUM.
BILL: NOAA POZNER AND JACK
PINTO, THEY WILL BE LAID TO REST
TODAY.
MARTHA: PETER, WHAT'S THE
LATEST?
>> Reporter: THE LATEST IS
POLICE ARE SAYING LOCAL
AUTHORITIES HAD NO CONTACT WITH
ADAM LANZA BEFORE FRIDAY.
THE LOCAL AUTHORITIES DON'T HAVE
ANYTHING ON RECORD OF THAT.
THEY DID SAY THERE ARE TWO ADULT
WITNESSES RECOVERING FROM
GUNSHOT WOUNDS.
THEIR TESTIMONY IS GOING TO BE
HELPFUL IN FIGURE OUT WHAT
HAPPENED INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
YOU HEARD THE POLICE SAY THEY
HAVE MAJOR CRIME DETECTIVES
WORKING 24-HOUR SHIFT.
THEY ARE GOING TO TRACE THE GUNS
THAT WERE USED AND THEY WILL
LOOK AT EVERY PIECE OF
AMMUNITION THAT WAS USED.
HUNDREDS OF ROUND FROM MULTIPLE
MAGAZINES.
>> EVERY SINGLE FACET OF THE
WEAPONS WILL BE ANALYZED.
EVERY ROUND OF AMMUNITION WILL
BE LOOKED AT FOR PHYSICAL
EVIDENCE.
I ALLUDED TO THE VOLUME OF ROUND
THAT WERE SEIZED AND RECOVERED.
EACH SINGULAR ROUND WILL BE
EXAMINED.
>> Reporter: YOU HEARD THERE
ARE MANY, MANY WITNESSES.
WE ARE TOLD WHEN THEY ARE
INTERVIEWED THEIR PARENT WILL BE
PRESENT AND THOSE INTERVIEWS
WILL BE DONE AS DELICATELY AS
POSSIBLE, MARTHA.
MARTHA: IT WILL BE VERY
DIFFICULT.
WE JUST SAW SOME VIDEO FROM LAST
NIGHT.
THE PRESIDENT IN WHAT HAS BECOME
ONE OF THE MOST DIFFICULT DUTIES
OF THE PRESIDENCY HAD TO MEET
WITH GRIEVING PARENT OF SMALL
CHILDREN IN THIS SITUATION.
HOW WAS HIS SPEECH AND HIS TIME
IN NEWTOWN RECEIVED BY THE
PEOPLE THERE?
>> REPORTER: IT WAS RECEIVED
REALLY WELL.
I WATCHED THE ENTIRE INTERFAITH
SERVICE AT A LOCAL RESTAURANT
WITH 30 PEOPLE FROM THE AREA.
THEY SAT IN COMPLETE SIREN FOR
THE HOUR AND A HALF.
THEY WERE EMOTIONAL BUT THEY
SEEMED HOPEFUL BASED ON THE
PLEDGE THE PRESIDENT MADE.
>> HERE AT NEWTOWN I COME TO
OFFER THE PRAYERS AND LOVER OF A
NATION.
I AM VERY MINDFUL THAT MERE
WORDS CANNOT MATCH THE DEPTHS OF
SORROW.
NOR CAN THEY HEAL YOUR WOUNDED
HEARTS.
>> Reporter: THE FOCUS HERE IN
NEWTOWN IS ON ALL THE FIRST
GRADER AND EDUCATORS WHO LOST
THEIR LIVES SO EARLY.
THEIR STORIES, THE MORE THEY
LEARN ARE HEARTBREAKING.
BUT THEY ARE IMPORTANT TO TELL.
YOU HAVE GOT 6-YEAR-OLD
CHARLOTTE BACON WHO DIED WEARING
A PING DRESS AND BOOTS HER MOM
WANTED TO KEEP SET ASIDE UNTIL
THE HOLIDAYS.
CHARLOTTE ABOUT KEPT BEGGING HER
AND IT ENDED UP BEING THE LAST
THING SHE WORE.
THERE IS ALSO RACHEL DIVINO AND
HER BOYFRIEND WAS GOING TO
PROPOSE AND CHRISTMAS EVE.
BEATER, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
PETER DOOCY.
THE CHURCH IN NEWTOWN WILL BE
THE HOST OF 10 FUNERALS THIS
WEEK AND NEXT WEEK.
IT REMINDS ME OF 9/11 WHEN WE
SAW MULTIPLE FUNERALS TAKING
PLACE IN LOCAL CHURCHES IN THIS
AREA.
VERY, VERY HARD FOR THESE
COMMUNITIES.
BILL: YOU CAN'T HIT A GOLF BALL
OR THROW A SNOWBALL IN THIS TOWN
WITHOUT HITTING A CHURCH OF SOME
DENOMINATION.
FAITH IS SO IMPORTANT TO THE
PEOPLE WHO LIVE IN NEWTOWN.
THERE IS A MAKESHIFT MEMORIAL.
THERE ARE MANY OF THEM SET UP
THROUGHOUT TOWN.
THIS IS THE AREA WHERE THEY SET
UP 26 CHRISTMAS TREES OVER THE
WEEKEND.
AND NOWER IN ALLOWING PEOPLE
FROM THE COMMUNITY TO WALK THE
HALF MILE DOWN THIS ROAD TO
PLACE FLOWERS OR LAY A WREATH OR
HANG AN ORNAMENT.
THIS IS THE CLOSEST YOU CAN GET
TO THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
YOU HAVE TO GO 100 YARD DOWN
DICKINSON LANE AND PEEL TO THE
RIGHT IN THE PARKING LOT BEFORE
THE SCHOOL REVEALS IN FRONT OF
YOU.
THIS IS HOW WE GRIEVE AND THIS
IS HOW SO MANY HAVE COME TO
RECOGNIZE THE LIVES TAKEN FROM
US.
THREE DAYS AGREE WE HAVE SEEN
SOME WOMEN COME DOWN FROM THE
TOWN AND HUG EACH OTHER AS THEY
GET CLOSE.
IF YOU WERE TO GO HALF A MILE
DOWN FROM THAT CHRISTMAS TREE
LOCATION YOU WOULD ARRIVE AT THE
ONLY TRAFFIC LIGHT IN SANDY
HOOK, AND WE WERE THERE A SHORT
TIME AGO.
THIS IS THE CHRISTMAS TREE SET
UP IN THE VILLAGE OF SANDY HOOK.
AND THERE ARE SO MANY POIGNANT
ORNAMENTS AND REMINDERS AND
ARTIFACTS GATHERED HERE.
THIS MEMORIAL HAS GROWN
ENORMOUSLY THE PAST FEW DAYS.
YOU LOOK AT SOME OF THE
CHRISTMAS BULBS.
THIS ONE OF NOAH POZNER.
, A LEGO STAND.
THIS CAUGHT MY EYE.
STATE POLICE OF CONNECTICUT.
WRAPPED AROUND A TEDDY BEAR.
THE POLICE HAVE BEEN SO
WONDERFUL AND SO PROFESSIONAL.
AND I THINK IT'S AN INDICATION
AND STRONG NOD TO THE PEOPLE OF
CONNECTICUT, THEY HAVE A LOT TO
BE PROUD OF WITH THIS POLICE
DEPARTMENT.
YOU SEE THE AREA, IT HAS GROWN
BY THE DAY.
THE BALLOONS AND TEDDY BEARS AND
THE WREATHS AND FLOWERS.
THIS CHRISTMAS TREE OVER HERE.
IT HAS THE NAMES -- IT'S SMALL
JUST LIKE A CHILD AT THAT AGE.
THERE IS CHASE THIS IS DAWN
HOCHSTRUNG.
AND EMILIE PARKER WHOSE FATHER
CAME OUT SATURDAY NIGHT AND HAD
SUCH A WONDERFUL TRIBUTE TO HIS
DAUGHTER.
THIS IS THE CENTER OF SANDY HOOK
FOREVER TO BE REMEMBERED WITH
PRAYERS AND THOUGHTS.
FOR THOSE WHO HAVE LEFT US.
FOREVER.
THIS IS A LOCAL NEWSPAPER FROM
DANBURY CALLED "THE NEWS TIMES."
IT HAS A PICTURE OF THE
PRESIDENT.
"TEACH THEM WELL" IN QUOTES.
YOU SEE THE BLACK BANNER OF 27
WHO LEFT US INCLUDING THE NAME
OF NANNY LANZA, THE MOTHER OF
ADAM LANZA, THE KILLER, AGE 20.
MORE IN A MOMENT.
WE EXPECT A BRIEFING AGAIN
SHORTLY.
WE'LL GET MORE INFORMATION.
IN THE MEANTIME WE ARE GOING TO
TALK TO LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE.
MY APOLOGIES.
SORRY ABOUT THAT.
WE'LL TRY AND PUSH THIS STORY
FORWARD.
MARTHA: YOU MAKE SUCH A GOOD
POINT ABOUT THE TROOPERS THERE
AND LIEUTENANT VANCE HAS BEEN SO
REMARKABLE, WHAT REAL BACKBONE
FOR THIS TOWN.
IT'S STRANGE TO SEE THAT
COMBINATION WHERE THERE SHOULD
BE CHRISTMAS GIFT TO SEE THE
JUXTAPOSITION OF THE MOURNING OF
THE NAMES OF THE YOUNG CHILDREN,
SO MANY OF WHOM WERE LOOKING
FORWARD TO CHRISTMAS WITH THEIR
FAMILIES.
WE MOURN THE LOSS OF THOSE YOUNG
CHILDREN AND ALL OF THE VICTIMS
AND WE ARE REMEMBERING SOME OF
THE HEROES WHO DIED PROTECTING
OTHERS.
THE ORNAMENTS EVEN MORE ON THOSE
TREES.
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG WAS THE
PRINCIPAL OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
BY ALL ACCOUNTS SHE LUNGED OUT
INTO THE HALLWAY AREA AND TOOK
ON THE KILLER TO TRY TO STOP HIM
AND SHE WAS ONE OF THE INITIAL
CASUALTIES OF THIS HORRIFIC
CRIME.
SHE IS CREDITED WITH ALERTED
CLASSES BEFORE SHE WAS KILLED
AND FELLOW COLLEAGUES WHO NEARLY
WALKED INTO THE LINE OF FIRE.
SHE WAS ABLE TO PROTECT THEM AS
WELL.
COLLEAGUES SAY SHE TREATED
EVERYBODY IN THAT SCHOOL AS
FAMILY.
>> JUST LIKE HER STUDENT.
SHE CARED FOR HER FAMILY.
SHE TALKED ABOUT THE FAMILY.
SHE WAS A GREAT MOTHER,
STEPMOTHER, A WIFE.
HER FAMILY LIVED IN OUR TOWN.
IT'S A SMALL COMMUNITY.
WE WOULD SEE EACH OTHER IN THE
GROCERY STORE.
I CONTINUALLY ASKED HER TO COME
BACK TO OUR SCHOOL SYSTEM BUT
SHE WAS HAPPY MOVING FORWARD
WITH HER CAREER.
IT'S A GREAT TRAGEDY.
OUR THOUGHTS AND PRAYERS GO OUT
TO HER FAMILY.
MARTHA: WE HEARD THE POLICE
UPDATE.
THE SHOOTER'S AUNT IS RELEASING
PERSONAL DETAILS OF THE
STRUGGLES HE FACED BEFORE THE
VIE SCHEDULE TOOK PLACE.
AND THE PARENTS OF TWO YOUNG
VICTIMS WILL BE THE FIR TO HAVE
THE FUNERALS TODAY IN THAT
TRAGEDY.
WE'LL DISCUSS THE ROLE OF
RELIGION IN AMERICA'S HEALING
PROCESS THIS WEEK AS WE TRY TO
FIND THE STRENGTH AMID FAITH FOR
SUCH DEVASTATING HEARTBREAK.
AND AS THE PRESIDENT ISSUES A
CALL FOR CHANGE TO COME FROM
THIS NATIONAL TRAGEDY WE'LL
DEBATE WHAT HE THINKS NEEDS TO
BE DONE TO MAKE SURE THAT THIS
NEVER HAPPENS AGAIN.
>> I HAVE BEEN REFLECTING ON
THIS.
IF WE ARE HONEST WITH OURSELVES
THE ANSWER IS NO.
WE ARE NOT DOING ENOUGH.
AND WE'LL HAVE TO CHANGE.
MARTHA: MONDAY MORNING NOW.
AMERICANS ARE STILL TRYING
TO MAKE SENSE OF THE TRAGEDY
THAT UNFOLDED IN NEWTOWN
LAST WEEK, IF SUCH A THING
COULD REALLY EVER HAPPEN.
WE'RE GETTING A BETTER
PICTURE OF SOME OF THE
PERSONAL ISSUES THAT PLAGUED
THIS SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA,
FROM FAMILY MEMBERS WHO
WATCHED HIS PARENTS
STRUGGLES WITH THEIR
TROUBLED SON.
>> I KNOW SHE HAD ISSUES
WITH SCHOOL.
SHE MENTIONED SHE WOUND UP
HOMESCHOOLING HIM.
SHE BATTLED WITH THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT.
IN WHAT CAPACITY I'M NOT
100% CERTAIN.
IF IT WAS BEHAVIOR OR
LEARNING DISABILITIES, I
DON'T KNOW.
HE WAS VERY, VERY BRIGHT
BOY.
IF SHE.
THEY WERE TYPE OF PARENTS
WHEN THEY WERE MARRIED AND
SEPARATE LATED IF KIDS HAD A
NEED THIS WOULD DEFINITELY
FILL IT.
MARTHA: BOY, SO MUCH
CONFUSION AND JUST TRYING TO
UNDERSTAND HOW DO YOU GET TO
THIS POINT?
HE WAS REPORTEDLY DEVASTATED
BY HIS PARENTS DIVORCE BACK
IN 2009.
HIS FATHER SAYS, QUOTE, WE
TWO ARE ASKING WHY, WHY.
IMAGINE WHAT HIS FAMILY IS
GOING THROUGH AS WELL
BECAUSE, WE'VE HEARD THAT
EVEN, FROM ONE OF THE LITTLE
GIRL, EMILY PARKER'S DAD
SAID HE FELT SYMPATHY FOR
THE FAMILY OF THE SHOOTER.
EVERYBODY OFFERING
CONDOLENCE ARES TO THE
FAMILIES OF THOSE LOST LOVED
ONES AND INSURED AS WELL.
PRESIDENT OBAMA USED HIS
SPEECH AT LAST NIGHT'S
PRAYER VIGIL IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, TO COMFORT A
SHATTERED COMMUNITY AND
GRIEF-STRICKEN NATION AND TO
CALL FOR CHANGE AS A RESULT.
>> WE JUST CAN'T TOLERATE
THIS ANYMORE.
THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
AND TO END THEM WE MUST
CHANGE.
WE WILL BE TOLD THAT THE
CAUSES OF SUCH VIOLENCE ARE
COMPLEX AND THAT IS TRUE.
NO SINGLE LAW, NO SET OF
LAWS CAN ELIMINATE EVIL FROM
THE WORLD OR PREVENT EVERY
SENSELESS ACT OF VIOLENCE IN
OUR SOCIETY.
BUT THAT CAN'T BE A AN
EXCUSE FOR INACTION.
MARTHA: SO WHAT NEEDS TO BE
DONE?
THE PRESIDENT RAISES AN
EXTREMELY IMPORTANT QUESTION
HERE.
IT IS WORTH TALKING ABOUT
AND REFLECTING ON THIS
MORNING.
WE ARE GLAD TO DO THAT THIS
MORNING WITH KIRSTEN POWERS,
"DAILY BEAST" COLUMNIST AND
FOX NEWS CONTRIBUTOR AND
TONY SAYING, FORMER PRESS
AIDE TO GOP
VICE-PRESIDENTIAL NOMINEE
AND JACK KEMP AND RADIO NEWS
SERVICE.
GOOD MORNING TO BOTH OF YOU.
AS WE TRY TO SHAKE OFF SO
TOM EXTENT AND MAKE REAL
ASSESSMENTS ABOUT IT.
YOU BOTH GREW UP ROUGHLY
WHEN I DID.
WE HAD FIRE DRILLS ONCE IN A
WHILE.
MY CHILDREN GO TO SCHOOL, WE
TALKED OVER THE WEEKEND.
THEY SAID OH, YEAH WE HAVE
THREE DIFFERENT KINDS OF
DRILLS WE DO.
ONCE A MONTH DO ROTATING
DRILL.
ONE TO GET AS FAR AWAY FROM
THE SCHOOL AS POSSIBLE.
IN THE OTHER WE'RE SUPPOSED
TO BARRICADE OURSELVES INTO
A ROOM.
THEY GO THROUGH THE RITUALS,
TONY, ON A REGULAR BASIS AS
KIDS DO ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
YOU HAVE SCHOOLS SAYING
WE'RE BRINGING IN ADDITIONAL
SECURITY.
WE DIDN'T GROW UP LIKE THIS.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
>> MARTHA, I THINK WE'RE SO
UNITED RIGHT NOW OVER THIS
TRAGEDY WHICH AFFECTS
ANYBODY.
ANY PERSON WITH A HEART BEAT
IN AMERICA SUFFERS FOR THE
FAMILIES AND LOST PEOPLE AND
CHILDREN ESPECIALLY IN
MASSACRE AND I THINK WE
SHOULD SEIZE THIS MOMENT TO
TRY TO WORK TOGETHER, WE'RE
NOT GOING TO SOLVE THIS
PROBLEM BUT WE COULD ADDRESS
CERTAIN ASPECTS OF IT.
BECAUSE ONE MAD MEN OR
SOCIOPATH OR DERANGED PERSON
WILL NEVER CONFORM OR SUBMIT
TO RATIONAL LAW.
TO THE PRESIDENT'S POINT,
THAT DOESN'T MEAN WE DON'T
TRY TO DO SOMETHING.
ONE.
IDEAS COME OUT IN THE WAKE
OF THIS, YOU DISCUSSED IT
WITH SENATOR LIEBERMAN, IS
THIS COMMISSION ON VIOLENCE
BECAUSE VIOLENCE IS SUCH A
MULTIDIMENSIONAL COMPLEX
ISSUE.
IT COMES PARTS OF THE
ENTERTAINMENT INDUSTRY.
COMES FROM THE BREAKDOWN
PERHAPS IN PEOPLE'S
FAMILIES.
BULLYING.
COMES FROM THE LACK OF FAITH
I THINK.
THE ADVOCATED IN OUR PARTS
OF OUR SOCIETY TODAY.
AND GUN CONTROL IS ALSO A
PART OF THAT CONVERSATION.
SO I THINK IF WE'RE ABLE TO
GET, MAYBE A GUY LIKE
JOE LIEBERMAN TO HEAD UP A
COMMISSION WITH A REAL
MANDATE TO ADDRESS WAYS
GOVERNMENT CAN REALLY
PROTECT CHILDREN I THINK WE
SHOULD PERHAPS START THAT
CONVERSATION.
MARTHA: FAMILY, VIOLENCE AND
GUNS.
THOSE ARE THE THREE WORDS,
KIRSTEN.
THE BREAKDOWN OF THE FAMILY.
EXTREME AMOUNT OF VIOLENCE
WE LIVE WITH AND SEE IN OUR
SOCIETY.
THESE ASSAULT WEAPONS THAT
ARE WAR WEAPONS, THAT ARE
PART OF THE CULTURE AS WELL,
KIRSTEN?
>> YEAH.
I MEAN PEOPLE TALK A LOT
ABOUT THE ASPECT OF THE
HOLLYWOOD AND VIDEOGAMES.
I'M NOT REALLY SURE WHAT THE
GOVERNMENT CAN DO ABOUT
THAT.
WE CAN LOOK AT IT AND
ADVOCATE PEOPLE DON'T
CONSUME THIS.
THERE IS VERY LITTLE WE CAN
DO TO STOP PEOPLE PUTTING IT
OUT.
THE TWO PLACES WHERE
GOVERNMENT CAN DO SOMETHING
ON MENTAL HEALTH ISSUE.
PROVIDING SUPPORT TO
PARENTS.
A LOT OF PARENTS WHO FACE
WHAT THE MOTHER OF THIS
SHOOTER, THIS KILLER FACED
WHICH IS MENTALLY ILL
CHILDREN AND THERE AREN'T A
LOT OF RESOURCES TO DEAL
WITH THEM.
IF PEOPLE WANT TO HAVE
SOMEONE COMMITTED WHO THEY
THINK IT IS DANGEROUS IT IS
VERY DIFFICULT.
SO THOSE THINGS NEED TO BE
LOOKED AT.
GUN CONTROL NEEDS TO BE
YES, IT'S TRUE A CRAZY
PERSON MAY GO OUT AND DO
SOMETHING CRAZY BUT IF THEY
DON'T HAVE A
SEMIAUTOMATICKIC IT WILL BE
A LOT HARDER FOR THEM TO
CAUSE THE KIND OF CARNAGE WE
SAW HERE.
WE HAVE TO LOOK AT THAT AND
LOOK AT SOME KIND OF
LIMITATIONS WE'RE WILLING TO
PUT ON SOME OF OUR RIGHTS.
MARTHA: YOU BOTH MAKE VERY
GOOD POINTS.
WE HAVE TO TALK ABOUT THE
ISSUE OF INSTITUTIONALIZING
AND WHY IT IS SO DIFFICULT.
ARE THERE TIMES WHEN THAT IS
APPROPRIATE ACTION T TAKE
TO PROTECT OTHERS.
QUICKLY, TONY.
>> SORRY.
TO KIRSTEN'S POINT, THERE IS
A BILL RIGHT NOW, H.R. 2600,
PEDIATRIC BRAIN INJURIES ARE
THE LEADING CAUSE OF DEATH
AND DISABILITY UNDER 25 IN
AMERICA AND LEADING CAUSE OF
MENTAL ILLNESS AND MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES IN CHILDREN
THAT END UP BECOMING
PROBLEMATIC.
HAS BIPARTISAN SUPPORT IN
THE HOUSE.
NEEDS A SPONSOR IN THE
SENATE.
THE PRESIDENT SHOULD
CONSIDER SUPPORTING THIS
INITIATIVE.
MARTHA: VERY GOOD POINT.
TONY, KIRSTEN, THANKS SO
MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
BILL: MARTHA, WE'LL SPEAK
WITH LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE
WHO WILL BE MY GUEST IN A
MOMENT.
HIS INVESTIGATORS ARE
WORKING THROUGH A MASSIVE
CRIME SCENE IN AND AROUND
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
A SHATTERED COMMUNITY COMING
TOGETHER TO GRIEVE AS
FUNERALS GET UNDERWAY TODAY.
TRY RUNNING FOUR.NING
A RESTAURANT IS HARD,
FORTUNATELY WE'VE GOT INK.
IT GIVES US 5X THE REWARDS
ON OUR INTERNET, PHONE
CHARGES AND CABLE,
PLUS AT OFFICE SUPPLY STORES.
REWARDS WE PUT RIGHT
BACK INTO OUR BUSINESS.
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
WE'VE EVER WANTED TO DO
AND INK HELPS US DO IT.
MAKE YOUR MARK
WITH INK FROM CHASE.
BILL: TWO FUNERALS PLANNED
FOR TODAY.
BOTH YOUNG BOYS AGES 6, TO
BEGIN ABOUT 1:00 THIS
AFTERNOON HERE IN NEW TOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WE WERE JUST TALKING WITH
POLICE OFFICERS WHO LED THE
INVESTIGATION HERE FROM DAY
ONE.
I WANT TO BRING THEM IN
RIGHT NOW, LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE FROM THE CONNECTICUT
POLICE DEPARTMENT AND
LIEUTENANT GEORGE SINKO FROM
THE NEWTOWN POLICE
DEPARTMENT.
GOOD MORNING TO BOTH OF YOU.
>> GOOD MORNING.
BILL: IN OUR LINE OF WORK WE
SEE A LET OF THIS.
NOTHING THAT COMPARES TO
WHAT HAPPENED 100 YARDS DOWN
DICKINSON LANE HERE.
YOU JENT MEN HAVE BEEN
OUTSTANDING SINCE DAY ONE.
I KNOW HOW INCREDIBLY
DIFFICULT THIS MUST BE FOR
BOTH OF YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME.
>> THANK YOU.
BILL: WHAT INFORMATION CAN
YOU PROVIDE ON THREATS OF
VARIOUS CHURCHES COLLING IN.
>> AS WE ALLUDE TO, UNDER NO
CIRCUMSTANCES ANYTHING FUNNY
ABOUT THIS.
OR CAN BE TREATED FUNNY.
THREATS OR STATEMENTS OF
HARM OR ANYTHING LIKE THAT
IS GOING TO BE FULLY
INVESTIGATED, FULLY
RESPONDED TO.
IF ANY VIOLATIONS OF STATE
LAW HAVE OCCURRED OR FEDERAL
LAW HAVE OCCURRED THEY WILL
BE PROSECUTED TO THE FULLEST
EXTENT OF THE LAW.
BILL: HOW MANY THREATS HAVE
YOU SEEN?
>> ONLY SEEN A COUPLE.
BILL: ONLINE ORIVELY?
>> TELEPHONE THREATS BUT,
HAVING IT REVIEWED BY THE
U.S. ATTORNEY AND STATE'S
ATTORNEY THEY HAVE INDICATED
THERE IS NO ROOM FOR THIS.
THERE IS NO ROOM FOR
ANYTHING TO MISLEAD
INVESTIGATORS, TO MAKE
STATEMENTS ON THE INTERNET
OR ONLINE OR SOCIAL MEDIA
PAGES ANYTHING ALONG THOSE
LINES THAT WOULD CAUSE HARM
TO THIS INVESTIGATION, SLOW
IT DOWN IN ANY CAPACITY.
THEREFORE THAT STATEMENT HAS
BEEN VERY FIRM AND VERY
CLEAR.
BILL: TOUGH QUESTION HERE.
HOW IMPORTANT IS IT TO THIS
INVESTIGATION TO TALK TO THE
FIVE, 6, 7-YEAR-OLD CHILDREN
WHO CAME RUNNING DOWN THIS
STREET ON FRIDAY MORNING?
>> I HAVE TO TELL YOU THAT
THE STATE POLICE DETECTIVES
WORKING WITH SUPPORT
AGENCIES AND NEWTOWN POLICE
DETECTIVES WILL HAVE A VERY,
VERY DIFFICULT TIME TALKING
WITH THESE PEOPLE, WITH THE
SURVIVORS AND ANY AND ALL
WITNESSES.
BUT THEY'RE GOING TO DO IT.
THEY WILL DO IT GENTLY,
APPROPRIATELY, WITH
APPROPRIATE SUPPORT AND
PARENTAL INVOLVEMENT.
CERTAINLY OUR INTENT TO PEEL
BACK THIS ONION, ANSWER
EVERY SINGLE QUESTION AND
PAINT A VERY CLEAR PICTURE
WHAT HAPPENED.
BILL: TO BE CLEAR, YOU CAN
NOT CONCLUDE YOUR
INVESTIGATION WITHOUT
TALKING TO THEM?
>> MOST PROBABLY, MOST
PROBABLY THEY'RE ALL GOING
TO HAVE TO BE TALKED TO.
BILL: IT WILL BE TOUGH AS
YOU POINT OUT.
LIEUTENANT, YOU SPENT A LOT
OF TIME WITH THE FAMILIES.
AND YOU'VE ASKED US TO KEEP
OUR DISTANCE AND WE HOPE WE
HAVE RESPECTED THAT.
WE BELIEVE WE HAVE AND WILL
CONTINUE TO DO THAT.
>> THANK YOU.
BILL: HOW ARE THEY DOING?
>> UNIMAGINABLE WHAT THEY'RE
FEELING RIGHT NOW.
I DON'T THINK THEY HAVE
STILL HIT THEM COMPLETELY.
IT WILL BE A LONG HEALING
PROCESS.
BILL: YOU THINK ABOUT THE
STAGES, FIRST OF SHOCK.
AND THEN IT'S GRIEF.
AND THEN COMES THE ANGER,
ARE WITH ARE THEY IN THAT
SERIES NOW?
>> YOU KNOW, THE CERTAINLY
THE SHOCK AND GRIEF IS IN
THERE.
WHAT, WE'VE HAD TO ENDURE
HERE IS UNIMAGINABLE.
OUR HEARTS GO OUT TO THESE
FAMILIES AND RIGHT NOW
THAT'S ALL WE'RE THINKING
ABOUT.
BILL: I TALKED TO MANY
PEOPLE IN TOWN AND THEY HAVE
TOLD ME EVERYBODY KNEW ADAM
LANZA.
HE WAS THE AWKWARD GUY WHO
ALWAYS STUCK OUT AND NO ONE
REALLY HAD AN IDEA ABOUT HOW
TO RELATE TO HIM.
WERE YOU AWARE OF HIM?
>> I HAVE NO DIRECT DEALINGS
WITH HIM.
WE REALLY DON'T HAVE A LOT
OF REPORTS ON HIM, AS FAR AS
AT THE POLICE DEPARTMENT.
SO --.
BILL: CRIMINAL SENSE HE HAS
NO RECORD.
SO THAT'S UNDERSTANDABLE.
>> HE IS ONE OF THOSE GUYS
THAT JUST, KIND OF FLEW
UNDER THE RADAR A LITTLE.
BILL: REALLY?
UNDER THE RADAR?
>> TRAGEDY.
BILL: YOU'RE GOING TO BRIEF
AGAIN THIS AFTERNOON, I
THINK AT 12 NOON.
YOU'VE BEEN VERY CAREFUL
ABOUT THE AMOUNT OF
INFORMATION YOU HAVE MADE
PUBLIC.
>> YES, SIR.
BILL: WHAT IS THE PROCESS
FOR YOU ABOUT IN TRYING TO
KEEP THINGS ACCURATE?
KNOWING WHEN YOU CONSIDER
THE FIRST 36 HOURS THERE HAS
BEEN A LOT OF INFORMATION
OUT THERE THAT'S BEEN PULLED
BACK.
>> IT IS IMPORTANT WE ARE
TIMELY AND ACCURATE TO
DISSEMINATE INFORMATION TO
THE PUBLIC.
WE WANT THE COMMUNITY, THE
STATE AND THE WORLD TO KNOW
EXACTLY WHAT IS GOING ON BUT
THERE ARE ALSO SOME ISSUES
WE NEED TO KEEP THE CARDS
CLOSE TO OUR CHEST AS WE
FURTHER THE INVESTIGATION.
WE DON'T WANT ANY
MISINFORMATION OUT THERE.
WE DON'T WANT ANY MISLEADING
INFORMATION.
WE WANT TO BE CLEAR, CONCISE,
ACCURATE.
WE WANT PEOPLE TO KNOW THIS
INVESTIGATION WILL TAKE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
MANY MONTHS TO COMPLETE.
WHEN WE COMPLETE IT WE'LL
HAVE A CRYSTAL CLEAR PICTURE
WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
BILL: THE KILLER HAD A
FATHER.
STILL DOES.
HE LIVES IN CONNECTICUT. THE RE?
>> I'M NOT FAMILIAR WITH
THAT UNFORTUNATELY.
I HAVEN'T DELVED INTO THAT
AS FAR AS MY PART OF
INVOLVEMENT HERE.
BUT OUR INVESTIGATORS WILL
DISSECT EVERY PIECE OF IT.
THE FAMILY MAKEUP.
THE HISTORY.
FAMILY.
RELATIVES, FRIENDS,
COWORKERS.
STUDENTS, ANYBODY THAT THE
SHOOTER HAD CONTACT WITH
WILL BE INTERVIEWED.
WILL BE PART OF OUR
CONCLUSION AND OUR
INVESTIGATION.
BILL: TO YOUR COLLEAGUE,
LIEUTENANT, DO YOU HAVE
ANYTHING TO ADD ON THE
RELATIONSHIP OF THE FATHER
AND?
>> WE HAVEN'T HAD ANY
CONTACT WITH THE FATHER.
YOU KNOW, AT THIS TIME WE
REALLY HAVE NOT HAD A LOT OF
DEALINGS WITH THAT FAMILY ON
THE POLICE LEVEL.
BILL: HE MADE A STATEMENT
OVER THE WEEKEND.
IS THERE SOMETHING ELSE
PLANNED WITH HIM?
AN INTERVIEW, A CONVERSATION?
>> CERTAINLY ANY INFORMATION
THAT CAN ASSIST US WE'RE
WILLING TO TALK TO ANYBODY
THAT CAN HELP US HERE.
BILL: YOU'RE SAYING YES ON
THAT?
>> WE'RE CERTAINLY GOING TO
INTERVIEW ALL FAMILY MEMBERS,
ALL FAMILY MEMBERS, THAT CAN
PROVIDE ANY INFORMATION ON
THE SHOOTER.
IT IS VERY IMPORTANT TO OUR
CONCLUSION.
BILL: LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE,
THANK YOU.
LT. GEORGE SINCO.
FROM THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT AND THE TOWN OF
NEWTOWN.
WE'LL SEE YOU AGAIN IN 90
MINUTES.
THANK YOU, GENTLEMEN.
LET'S GO BACK TO NEW YORK
AND MARCH WITH MARTHA THERE.
MARTHA: THOSE TWO GENTLEMEN
HAVE BEEN STRONG LEADERS FOR
THIS COMMUNITY THROUGHOUT
THE COURSE OF THIS WEEKEND
AND WE CONTINUE TO COULD SO.
AMERICANS STRUGGLE TO COME
TO TERMS ABOUT THIS
SHOOTING.
THEY TURN TO RELIGION, FAITH,
SOME SENSE OF UNDERSTANDING
ABOUT ALL OF THIS.
THEY TRY TO FIND SOME SORT
OF HOPE IN THE MIDDLE OF ALL
OF THIS HEARTBREAK.
>> THEY WILL MOVE ON.
WE WILL NEVER FORGET.
WE WILL GET BETTER
MARTHA: WE GOT THE ANSWER TO A
BURNING POLITICAL QUESTION THIS
MORNING, AND THAT WAS WHO WILL
BE THE NEXT SENATOR FROM SOUTH
CAROLINA WHO WILL TAKE OVER THE
SPOT FOR JIM DEMINT WHO LEFT TO
RUN THE HERITAGE FOUNDATION.
THE NEW SENATOR WILL BE THIS
GENTLEMAN, REPRESENTATIVE TIM
SCOTT.
HE WAS APPOINTED BY NIKKI HALEY,
AT HER DISCRETION IT WAS HER
ABILITY TO MAKE THAT DECISION AS
SENATOR FROM SOUTH CAROLINA.
IT LOOKS HOW THAT AFFECTS THE
POLITICAL PICTURE IN THE
SENATE.
THAT NEWS BREAKING EARLIER THIS
MORNING.
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S TURN OUR ATTENTION TO THE
ON GOING CRISIS IN SYRIA.
NEW ATTACKS BEING LAUNCHED IN
THE TOWN OF DARAH AS BATTLES
RAGE ON AT A REFUGEE CAMP IN
DAMASCUS.
THEY SAY THE ARMY CANNOT DEFEAT
THE REBELS SEEKING TO TOP THE
PRESIDENT'S REGIME.
WHERE DOES THAT LEAVE US?
LELAND VITTERT JOINS US LIVE
FROM JERUSALEM WHERE HE IS
WATCHING THE STORY UNFOLD.
HOW SIGNIFICANT IS THAT
STATEMENT BY THE VICE
PRESIDENT?
>> Reporter: IN MANY WAYS,
MARTHA IT IS THE STATEMENT OF
THE OBVIOUS.
WHAT IS SO IMPORTANT IS WHO IS
SAYING IT.
THIS MAY BE THE BEGINNING OF
SOMEONE VERY CLOSE TO PRESIDENT
BASHAR AL-ASSAD LOOKING TO
NEGOTIATE AND EXIT, EITHER FOR
HIMSELF OR FOR A LARGER GROUP OF
THE BASHAR AL-ASSAD REGIME.
IT IS BOOKING INCREASINGLY CLEAR
AS WE ARE WATCHING THE BATTLES
GET CLOSER AND CLOSER TO
DAMASCUS THAT THE REBELS ARE
STARTING AT LOWE'S TO GAIN THE
UPPER HAND.
THEY ARE GETTING WEAPONS FROM A
NUMBER OF GULF COUNTRIES, THEY
ARE BECOMING BETTER TRAINED AND
ORGANIZED.
THEY'VE HAD SOME SIGNIFICANT
VICTORIES HERE IN THE PAST AND
THE GOVERNMENT FORCES CONTINUE
TO FALL APART IN LARGE PART,
ALTHOUGH THE CIVIL WAR IS STILL
RAGING ON, MANY SAY NEITHER SIDE
IS GOING TO BE ABLE TO WIN.
THE QUESTION IS HAS PRESIDENT
R-R BASHAR AL-ASSAD OR IN THIS
MATTER THE VICE PRESIDENT BEGUN
TO LOOK FOR A WAY OUT, WITH SO
GRAND NEGOTIATIONS.
THAT'S WHAT THE VICE PRESIDENT
TALKED ABOUT IN HIS INTERVIEW
WITH A LEBANESE NEWSPAPER
THERE.
THIS CONTINUES AS THE VIOLENCE
IS NOT ONLY GOING BETWEEN THE
REBELS AND OF COURSE THE SYRIAN
TROOPS BUT ALSO AFFECTING A
NUMBER OF CIVILIANS.
SOME OF THE VIDEO THAT WE HAVE
TO SHOW YOU FROM A PALESTINIAN
REFUGEE CAMP WHERE THERE HAS
BEEN ONGOING FIGHTING AND A
RECENT ATTACK BY GOVERNMENT
TROOPS IS GRUESOME TO SAY THE
LEAST.
THERE ARE A NUMBER OF SHOTS THAT
WE HAD TO EDIT OUT BECAUSE IT
GOT SO BAD THERE AT THAT SCENE.
THE U.N. HAS STEPPED IN TO TALK
ABOUT THE AMOUNT OF CIVILIANS
WHO ARE NOW IN HARM'S WAY.
IT'S BECOMING AN INCREASINGLY
DIFFICULT SITUATION TO TELL WHO
IS ON WHICH SIDE THERE INSIDE
THE SYRIAN CIVIL WAR.
THERE ARE A LOT OF THOUGHTS,
MARTHA THAT EVEN IF PRESIDENT
BASHAR AL-ASSAD AND HIS REGIME
LEAVE SOME TIME SOON OR IN THE
COMING MONTHS THAT MAY BE THE
BEGINNING OF A NEW CHAPTER IN
THE CIVIL WAR RATHER THAN SOME
GRAND PEACE THAT WOULD ALLOW
THESE THOUSANDS, IF NOT TENS OF
THOUSANDS AND MILLIONS OF
CIVILIANS WHOSE LIVES ARE IN
DANGER TO BE BACK SAFELY AT
HOME.
MARTHA: WE HAVE SEEN THAT THE
CHANGE OF POWER CAN SOMETIMES
NOT GO SMOOTHLY.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
LET'S GO TO BILL IN NEWTOWN.
BILL: WE ARE JUST A FEW HOURS
AWAY FROM THE FIRST OF DOZENS OF
FUNERALS TO BEGIN HERE IN
NEWTOWN IN SANDY HOOK,
CONNECTICUT.
WE KNOW THE FIRST RESPONDERS
POSSIBLY SAVED EVEN MORE LIVES
AS HUNDREDS OF ROUNDS OF
AMMUNITION UNUSED WERE FOUND
INSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
THAT IS NEXT WHEN WE CONTINUE ON
THE TRAGEDY HERE AT SANDY HOOK
IN A MOMENT.
WE'RE ALL HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR IN THE GULF,
WE'VE DIDED TO
PUT ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
'CAUSE ALL OUR STATES ARE GREAT.
AND NOW IS WHEN THE GULF
GETS EVEN BETT.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE OR
JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
ENJOY THE WILDLIFE
AND NATURAL BEAUTY.
AND DON'T FORGET
OUR AMAZING SEAFOOD.
SOOME TO THE GULF,
YOU'LL HAVE A GREAT TIME.
ESPECIALLY IN ALABAMA.
YOU MEAN MISSISSIPPI.
THAT'S FLORIDA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP AND ALL
OF US WHO CA THE GULF HOME.
BILL: WE KNOW THE ATTACK LASTED
ONLY TEN MINUTES AND IT WAS THE
SIRENS OF THE FIRST RESPONDERS
THAT FORCED THE KILLER TO TURN
HIS OWN GUNS AND OWN AMMUNITION
ON HIMSELF AND TAKE HIS LIFE.
BUT THAT WAS AFTER SO MANY YOUNG
LIVES WERE TAKEN FROM US.
WE ARE AT THE END OF THE ROAD
ACROSS THE STREET FROM THE FIRE
HOUSE HERE WHERE SO MANY DOZENS
AND DOZENS, IF NOT HUNDREDS OF
YOUNG CHILDREN FROM KINDERGARTEN
TO AGE FOUR AROUND THIS TIME,
THREE DAYS AGO, CAME HERE TO GET
AWAY FROM THE CARNAGE THEY HAD
JUST LEFT AND TO MEET THEIR
MOTHERS AND THEIR FATHERS WHO
CAME TO FIND THEM AND BRING THEM
HOME.
IF YOU GO DOWN THE ROAD HERE
ABOUT A HALF MILE YOU WILL FIND
THE ONLY TRAFFIC LIGHT IN THIS
TINY, WONDERFUL TOWN.
WE WERE THERE A SHORT TIME AGO.
THE STATE TROOPERS THAT ARE SET
UP AT THAT INTERSECTION PREVENT
A LOT OF TRAFFIC FRANKLY FROM
MOVING DOWN THAT ROAD.
IF YOU WENT DOWN THE ROAD ABOUT
500 YARDS YOU WOULD ARRIVE AT
THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
THIS IS SUCH A BEAUTIFUL VILLAGE
OF SANDY HOOK.
IT'S BEEN INVADED BY, FRANKLY SO
MUCH MEDIA AND TRAFFIC EVEN AT
7:30 IN THE MORNING.
YOU CAN IMAGINE IN DECEMBER WITH
THE SNOWFALL HOW BEAUTIFUL THIS
VILLAGE IS WITH A RIVER THAT
CUTS RIGHT THROUGH TOWN, AND THE
SIGNS NOW THAT ARE SET UP, ONE
AFTER THE OTHER, AFTER THE
OTHER, IN PARTICULAR THIS ONE
HERE, REST EASY, ANGELS, 12-14
12-14-12.
AND THREE DAYS LET'S ON 12-17,
TWO FUNERALS GET UNDERWAY TWO
HOURS FROM NOW.
MARTHA, I HAVE LEARNED THAT ONE
OF THE FIRST POLICE OFFICERS ON
THE SCENE IS ABOUT 25 YEARS OLD,
HE HASN'T SPOKEN PUBLICLY YET.
HE'S A U.S. MARINE, A VETERAN
FROM THE WAR IN AFGHANISTAN, AND
WHAT HE SAW INSIDE THAT SCHOOL
FAR ECLIPSESS ANYTHING HE CAME
ACROSS IN THE WAR ON TERROR
OVERSEAS IN THE DESERTS AND
MOUNTAINS OF AFGHANISTAN.
BACK TO YOU.
MARTHA: IT'S GOING TO BE VERY
DIFFICULT FOR THOSE FIRST
RESPONDERS TO THAT SCENE TO
EVER -- THEY WILL NEVER BE ABLE
TO GET THOSE IMAGES OUT OF THEIR
MINDS AND EVERYBODY WILL TRY TO
MOVE FORWARD IN SOME WAY, SHAPE
OR FORM, BILL.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
BACK HERE IN NEW YORK WE WANT TO
TURN OUR ATTENTION TO THIS STORY
THIS MORNING, SECRETARY OF STATE
HILLARY CLINTON IS SAID TO BE AT
HOME RECOVERING FROM A
CONCUSSION TODAY AFTER A FALL
THAT SHE SUSTAINED WHEN SHE
FAINTED DUE TO A STOMACH VIRUS.
THE STATE DEPARTMENT ANNOUNCED
ALL OF THIS OVER THE WEEKEND.
WE WERE AWAITING THE RESULTS OF
AN INDEPENDENT REVIEW OF THE
TERROR ATTACK IN BENGHAZI.
THE DETAILS OF WHICH EVERYBODY
LOOKS FORWARD TO LEARNING, AND
MANY HAD HOPED WOULD ARRIVE
BEFORE THE ELECTION.
NOW WE ARE LEARNING THAT
MRS. CLINTON WILL NOT TESTIFY
BEFORE THE HOUSE AND SENATE
PANELS ON THURSDAY AS WAS
EXPECTED ABOUT THAT DEADLY
SEPTEMBER 11th ASSAULT, AND
HERE ON THAT CONGRESSMAN PETER
KING.
>> TO REALLY FIND OUT WHAT
HAPPENED ULTIMATELY I BELIEVE
SECRETARY CLINTON WILL HAVE TO
TESTIFY.
I HAVE A GREAT RESPECT FOR
SECRETARY CLINTON AND NO ONE
WOULD KNOW MORE ABOUT THIS THAN
SHE WOULD AND NO ONE WOULD BE IN
A POSITION REALLY TO ANSWER THE
TOUGH QUESTIONS MORE THAN
SECRETARY CLINTON.
ONCE SHE RECOVERS I THINK IT'S
IMPORTANT SHE TESTIFY.
>> JOHNNY ISAACSON JOINS ME, A
MEMBER OF THE FOREIGN RELATIONS
COMMITTEE THAT WOULD BE HEARING
THIS TESTIMONY.
GOOD MORNING, GOOD TO HAVE YOU
WITH US TODAY.
>> TKP MORNINGGOOD MORNING,
MARTHA.
MARTHA
MARTHA: WE HEARD LAST WEEK THAT
SHE CANCELED A TRIP BECAUSE OF A
STOMACH VIRUS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK OF THE FACT
THAT SHE WILL NOT TESTIFY AND IN
HER PLACE WE WILL HEAR FROM
OFFICIALS WILLIAM BURNS AND
THOMAS NEADS.
>> WE HOPE THE SECRETARY
RECOVERS SOON, CONCUSSIONS CAN
BE BAD.
EVENTUALLY I THINK THE SECRETARY
OF STATE SHOULD TESTIFY.
SECRETARY BURNS IS A VERY
COMPETENT INDIVIDUAL BUT THIS IS
A TRAGIC LOSS OF A U.S.
AMBASSADOR, THE FIRST LOSS OF AN
AMBASSADOR SINCE 1979, OBVIOUS
BREAK DOWNS IN SECURITY.
WE NEED TO MAKE SURE WE FIND OUT
ANSWERS TO ALL THE QUESTIONS AND
MAKE SURE WE DRAW THE LINE SO IT
NEVER HAPPENS AGAIN.
MARTHA: THE COMMITTEE WILL HEAR
WE UNDERSTAND FROM FORMER
AMBASSADOR THOMAS PICKERING AND
RETIRED ADMIRAL MIKE MULLEN THE
FORMER CHIEF OF STAFF.
THE ONE LINK WE DON'T HAVE STILL
IS THE ADMINISTRATION, THE WHITE
HOUSE, IN TERMS OF THE REQUESTS
THAT WE KNOW CAME THROUGH FROM
AMBASSADOR CHRIS STEVENS FOR
MORE SECURITY IN BENGHAZI.
YOU KNOW, WHAT ARE THE BIG HOLES
IN THE STORY THAT YOU BELIEVE
NEED TO BE FILLED IN BY SOMEBODY
WHO WOULD BE PRIVY TO ALL THAT
INFORMATION?
>> WELL, YOU JUST HIT THE HEART
OF THE STORY AND THAT IS WHY THE
ADMINISTRATION WOULD PUT SUSAN
RICE ON THE POINT OF THE SPEAR
ON THE SUNDAY AFTER THE ATTACKS
WITH INFORMATION THAT I DON'T
THINK THEY BELIEVED TO BE
TOTALLY KREFPBLGT AND NOW WE
KNOW IT'S NOT CORRECT AT ALL.
THAT IS THE MOST IMPORTANT
REASON THE SECRETARY SHOULD
TESTIFY, AND WE OWE THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE THE FACTS AND ALL THE
FACTS.
>> WE OF.
MARTHA FACTS.
MARTHA: WE ALL UNDERSTAND AN
ILLNESS AND THE TIME TO RECOVER
FOR SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON.
AND WE HOPE SHE DOES THAT IN A
QUICK WAY IT DOES SEEM ODD IN
TERMS OF SUSAN RICE THAT HILLARY
CLINTON WASN'T AVAILABLE THAT
SUNDAY EITHER TO COME OUT AND
SPEAK TO EVERYBODY AT HOME, AND
AROUND THE COUNTRY ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED IN BENGHAZI, AND NOW
THIS OTHER DELAY.
SHE IS STEPPING DOWN IN JANUARY,
NOW WE ARE HEARING THAT SENATOR
KERRY IS LIKELY TO BE THE NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE.
IT RAISES A QUESTION WHETHER OR
NOT WE'LL EVER KNOW WHAT SHE
KNOWS ABOUT THIS SITUATION.
>> I THINK THE ADMINISTRATION
REALIZES WE'LL NEVER HAVE
CLOSURE ON THE FACTS IN THIS
CASE WITHOUT THE SECRETARY'S
TESTIMONY.
I'VE NEVER SEEN HER SHY AWAY
FROM A FIGHT OR FROM ANY
QUESTIONS, AND I'M SURE SHE WILL
WHEN SHE'S RECOVERED.
MARTHA: YOU DO EXPECT THAT YOU
WILL STILL HEAR HER TESTIMONY
IN -- HAVE YOU BEEN GIVEN ANY
TIMEFRAME AS TO WHEN THAT MIGHT
BE?
>> I HAVE NOT.
BUT I CAN TELL YOU ONE THING,
I'VE REVIEWED ENOUGH OF THE
TKOUPBLTS THE STATE DEPARTMENT
HAS GIVEN ME, I'VE SEEN ENOUGH
OF THE SECURITY TAPES THAT WERE
FILMED THE NIGHT OF THE
INCIDENT.
I'VE SEEN THE HISTORY THAT LED
UP TO IT.
WE HAD A TERRIBLE FAILURE OF
SECURITY TO PROTECT THE U.S.
AMBASSADOR.
WE EITHER ACTED OR DIDN'T ACT ON
INFORMATION WE HAD.
WE NEED FULL CLOSURE ON THIS.
FULL TESTIMO THE
FACTS ON THE TABLE AND ASSURE
OUR DIPLOMATES AROUND THE WORLD
THAT NEVER, EVER AGAIN WE WILL
PUT THEM IN HARM'S WAY LIKE
THIS.
MARTHA: THERE ARE THOSE IN YOUR
CAMP THAT BELIEVE THAT THE
ANSWERS ARE VERY IMPORTANT.
SENATOR WE HOPE YOU GET THEM.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR BEING
WITH US THIS MORNING.
>> THANK YOU, MARTHA.
BILL: JACK PINTO, NOAHPOSNER,
TWO YOUNG BOYS AGE SIX.
THEIR FUNERALS BEGIN IN TWO
HOURS, AND OUR COVERAGE
CONTINUES FROM NEWTOWN ON YET
ANOTHER DAY FROM SANDY HOOK.
[ fishing rod casting line,
marching band playing ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THE RHYTHM OF LIFE.
[ whistle blowing ]
WHERE DO YOU HEAR THAT BEAT?
CAMPBELL'S HEALTHY REQUEST SOUP
LETS YOU HEAR IT...
IN YOUR HEART.
[ basketball bouncing ]
HEART HEALTHY.
GREAT TASTE.
MMM...
[ Male Announcer ] SOUNDS GOOD.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
WHEN JENNA LEE AND I JOIN YOU IN
TEN MINUTES A LOOK INSIDE THE
INVESTIGATION AS TO WHAT
HAPPENED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOLment WHAT
INVESTIGATORS HOPE TO FIND THAT
WILL BE THE KEY TO UNLOCKING THE
MYSTERY BEHIND THE MOTIVE.
NEW DETAILS ON THE BENGHAZI
ATTACK EXPECTED TODAY.
WHAT LED UP TO THE
SEPTEMBER 11th AMBUSH ON OUR
CONSULATE TO LEFT FOUR AMERICANS
DEAD.
THE CHANGING FACE OF THE U.S.
SENATE, A MAJOR ANNOUNCEMENT AN
HOUR FROM NOW ON WHO IS TO
REPLACE SENATOR JIM DEMINT AND
WHAT IT MEANS FOR THE FUTURE OF
THE PARTY.
IT'S ALL COMING UP "HAPPENING
NOW."
BILL: JON, THANK YOU.
THE PARENTS OF TWO SIX-YEAR-OLD
BOYS GET READY FOR THE FIRST
FUNERALS IN THE AFTERMATH OF THE
DAMAGE REHEAR IN NEWTOWN.
WHILE NOAH POSNER AND JACK PINTO
MAY BE THE FIRST LAID TO REST
THEY WILL NOT BE THE LAST, AGES
SIX BOTH OF THEM.
FATHER JOHN NAN MORRIS IS A FOX
NEWS CONTRIBUTOR.
AND AUTHOR SPIRROW JOINS US
ALSO.
YOU CAN ASK YOURSELF WHY, YOU
CAN TRY AND FIGURE OUT ANSWERS,
WHETHER IT'S GUN VIOLENCE, OR
WHETHER IT'S VIDEO GAMES -RBLGS
O, MOVIES, MENTAL HEALTH,
RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN A PARENT
AND CHILD.
PUT ALL OF THAT ASIDE AND LOOK
AT IT IN A SIMPLER WAY, THERE
ARE TWO FORCES IN THIS WORLD.
ONE IS GOOD AND ONE IS EVIL.
LUCKILY THE GOOD USUALLY WINS,
BUT IN THIS CASE THE EVIL WON
OUT.
>> I THINK YOU'RE ONTO
SOMETHING.
AT THE SAME TIME WE CAN'T SAY
THE DEVIL MADE HIM DO IT,
RIGHT?
IN WALKING THROUGH THIS FIRE OUT
AND BEING WITH THE PEOPLE IN THE
BACK HERE IN THE MAKESHIFT
MEMORIAL, THEY ARE TELLING ME WE
GOING TO BE BETTER, WE ARE GOING
TO BE BETTER.
I THINK WHAT YOU SAID, BILL, YES
WE HAVE FORCES OF EVIL IN OUR
OWN LIVES, WE HAVE FORCES OF
GOOD.
IT'S TIME TO DOUBLE DOWN ON
LOVE.
IT JUST DOESN'T TAKE A VILLAGE
IT TAKES EVERYONE IN THAT
VILLAGE.
BILL: LET ME GET THE RABBI IN
HERE.
ONCE THEY THEY GET THE GOOD IS
ARGUE WITH THE GOOD AND MAKE THE
GOOD GO AGAINST THE GOOD.
HOW DO WE GO ABOUT UNDERSTANDING
THAT IN YOUR VIEW.
>> WHEN WE HAVE THESE EVENTS,
WHAT THEY ARE REALLY ARE JOLTS,
NATIONAL JOLTS THAT SHOULD
CATAPULT US TO AN UNDERSTANDING
OF THE VULNERABILITY OF LIFE BUT
THEREFORE THE SERIOUSNESS IN
WHICH WE HAVE A APPROACH LIFE
AND THE PRECIOUS NECESSARY OF
LIFE.
PRECIOUSNESS OF LIFE.
AFTER THESE EVENTS IF WE CAN
LOVE MORE AND REGARD MORE AND
UNDERSTAND THE APPRECIATE
SHESNESS OF OUR FAMILY AND
COUNTRY THERE IS SOMETHING EVIL
CANNOT DEFEAT AND THAT IS THE
WONDERFUL SPIRIT OF MAN TO SEE
THE GOOD, THE PRECIOUS THE
SACRED.
BILL: WELL STATED, THANK YOU,
RABBI.
AND THANK YOU, FATHER.
I APPRECIATE THAT.
LET'S GO BACK TO NEW YORK
AGAIN.
MARTHA: A SHORT TIME AWAY FROM
THE FIRST OF DOZENS OF FUNERALS
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
AS A COMMUNITY AND THE NATION WE
GRIEVE THE LOSS OF THESE
CHILDREN, THEIR TEACHERS, THEIR
PRINCIPALS AND WE HAVE THE
LATEST DEVELOPING DETAILS IN
THIS INVESTIGATION.
POLICE ARE EXPECTED TO HOLD
ANOTHER BRIEFING ABOUT AN HOUR
FROM NOW.
IN THE MEANTIME WE'LL BE RIGHT
BACK.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
PROGRESSIVE DIRECT AND OTHER
CAR INSURANCE COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
CALL OR CLICK TODAY.
MARTHA: LOT OF THOUGHTS TODAY ON
HOW WE GOT HERE, HOW THIS
TRAGEDY HAPPENED, BILL, AND TALK
ABOUT ASSAULT WEAPONS WHICH WILL
COME UP, DIANNE FEINSTEIN HAS
INTRODUCED A BILL THAT WILL BE
OUT IN JANUARY.
ALSO ISSUES OF MENTAL HEALTH AND
INSTITUTION IN A LIIZATION AND
DISCUSSIONS THAT NEED TO BE
HAD.
IN THE END YOU THINK ABOUT THESE
CHILDREN AND THEIR FAMILIES AND
THE SIBLINGS OF THESE CHILDREN
WHO ARE LOST, AND YOUR HEART --
YOU JUST WANT TO WRAP THEIR ARM