DOESN'T HAVE TO INTERFERE
THEIR LIFE.
WILL IT INFLUENCE, YES.
BUT THE COMMUNITY CAN COME
TOGETHER AND HEAL ONE ANOTHER
IF IT LANDLES IT PROPER LOW
AND ITS LIKE THEY ARE MOVING
THAT WAY.
>> ONE PROBLEM 150,000
SCHOOLINGS.
>> I HAVE A LOT OF MEP.
AND TELL YOU WHAT.
YOU SEE THOSE KIDS COMING OUT
IN THE LINE.
ONE LITTLE GIRL WAS CRYING AND
THE GIRL ON THE SMILE ON THE
FACE THEY REACT DIFFERENTLY.
>> OUR THOUGHT PRAYERS ARE
WITH THE TOWN AND OBVIOUSLY
WITH THE FAMILY.
STAY TUNED WITH THE CONTINUOUS
COVERAGE.
GRETA IS NEXT.
>> THIS IS IT A FOX NEWS
ALERT.
NEW INFORMATION ABOUT THE
ABSOLUTE UNTHINKABLE.
MURDER OF 27 PEOPLE.
20 OF THEM MERE CHILDREN SO
SMALL THEY DID NOT COME UP TO
OUR WAIST.
THE INDESCRIBABLE HORROR BEGAN
HOURS AGO WHEN UNSUSPECTED
PARENTS DROPPED THEIR
KINDERGARTEN AGE AND FOURTH
AGE OFF TO SCHOOL.
PARENTS COULDN'T HAVE
ANTICIPATE WHAT WAS ABOUT TO
HAPPEN.
A KILLER WALKS IN THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND
STARTS SHOOTING.
WE ARE LEARNING NEW
INFORMATION TONIGHT AND WE'LL
HAVE IT THROUGHOUT THE HOUR.
WE'LL START WITH RICK WHO IS
WITH THE LATEST.
WHO IS THE KILLER.
>> WE KNOW HIS NAME ADAM LANZA
AND LIVED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT WITH HIS MOTHER
NANCY WHO WAS SHOT DEAD IN HER
BED IN HER HOME THAT SHARED
WITH THE SHOOTER.
HE TOOK HER CAR AND AT LEAST
THREE WEAPONS AND MAYBE MORE.
GLOCK AND HOUR AND M-4 ASSAULT
RIFLE ASK WENT TO THE SCHOOL
WHERE HIS MOTHER WORKED AS A
SUBSTITUTE TEACHER AND GOT
THROUGH SECURITY AND WENT TO
TWO ROOM ONE AREA OF THE
SCHOOL AND BEGAN TO SHOOT
CHILDREN AND ADULTINGS.
HE SHOT 20 KIDS.
18 DIED AT THE SCENE AND TWO
IN THE HOSPITAL DIED.
HE SHOT SIX ADULTS INCLUDING
THE PRINCIPAL AND TOOK HIS OWN
LIFE HAS POLICE GOT TO THE
SCHOOL.
>> IS THERE ANY REPORT ON WHAT
HIGH WAS SAYING OR ANYTHING
PECULLIAR ABOUT HIM.
>> A SIX YEAR OLD BOY SAID THE
SHOOTER CAME IN AND SHOT THE
TEACHER AND THE BOY RAN OUT
AND THAT SHOOTER DIDN'T SAY A
SANDWICH WORD.
WE HEARD FROM THE SHOOTER'S
BROTHER THAT HE WAS LEARNING
DISABLED AND MAY HAVE BEEN
AUTISTIC.
>> AND THE MOTHER WAS SUPPOSED
TO TEACH TODAY?
>> WE DON'T KNOW THAT EITHER.
WE KNOW THAT THE YOUNG MAN
WOKE UP THIS MORNING AT HOME
AND SHOT HIS MOTHER IN THE
HOME AND TOCK HER CAR AND GUNS
AND SCHOOL WHERE SHE WORKED
AND BEGAN THE RAMPAGE.
NTHIS IS UNTHINKABLE.
THE IDEA OF WALKING IN THE
CLASS ROM AND JUST SHOOTING
CHILDREN .
>> LITTLE KIDS.
FIVE OR SIX YEAR OLD KIDS
DEFENSELESS AND INNOCENT AND
IT MAKES NO SENSE AT ALL.
>> AND A PRINCIPAL AND OTHER
ADULTS.
>> APPARENTLY THERE WERE
MORNING ANNOUNCEMENTS GOING ON
WHEN THE SHOOTINGS BEGAN AND
THEY HEARD SCREAMS OVER THE PA
SYSTEM IN ORDER TO HEARING THE
GUN FIRE RINGING THROUGH THE
HALLWAYS AND THEY WERE FIRED
IN AN AREA WHERE THE MORNING
ANNOUNCEMENTS WERE BEING MAD.
CHILDREN, 20 OF THEM MURDER
WHERE THEY SHOULD BE SAFE.
RAY, YOUR THOUGHTS TONIGHT.
>> YOU ARE TALKUG TO ME, AND I
DON'T KNOW, 12 OR 13 HOURS
AFTER THIS I AM SO NUMB AND I
AM CRYING AND EMOTIONAL FOR
MOST OF THE DAY.
AND SPEAKING WITH WORK
ASSOCIATES THAT WORKED WITH ME
AT THE SCHOOL AND FAMILY AND
FRIENDS THAT HAVE BEEN CALLING
AND AT THIS POINT, I AM NUMB.
>> RAY, YOU N THE
SHOOTER BEFORE OR HEAR
ANYTHING ABOUT HIM IN THE
COMMUNITY?
>> NO, NO.
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
I LEFTLET SCHOOL AND WE
GENERALLY WORKED TO NINE OR
9:30 AND THEN LEAVE.
THE STUDENTS COME TO CLASS AND
THAT'S WHEN WE TURN THEM OVER
TO THE REGULAR TEACHER AND
FIVE MINUTES MAYBE, THAT WHEN
WE LEFT THIS OCCURRED .
IT IS SO UNTHINKABLE RAY THAT
THIS COULD HAPPEN.
I CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT YOUR IS
GOING THROUGH TONIGHT.
WHERE DO YOU BEGIN TO PUT THE
SCHOOL BACK TOGETHER AND HEAL
THESE FAMILIES?
>> YOU KNOW, YOU TELL ME,
PLEASE.
IT IS SO UNBELIEVABLE.
WE ARE ALL LOOKING AT EACH
OTHER.
I JUST CAME FROM THIL AT --
VIGIL AT THE CHURCH AND THERE
WERE HUNDREDS AND HUNDREDS OF
PEOPLE THERE.
AND THEY WERE -- WE COULDN'T
BELIEVE THAT WHY ARE GOING TO
HAVE -- THIS IS THE SECOND
GREATEST MASS CURE IN THE
HISTORY OF THE UNITED STATES .
RAY, THANK YOU.
>> AND TONIGHT MEMBERS OF THE
GRIEF STRIKEN COMMUNITY
GATHERING FOR A MEMORIAL
SERVICE.
MOLLY IS OUTSIDE OF THE CHURCH
WHERE THE SERVICE WAS HELD.
MOLLY, WE ARE AT ONE OF THE
CHURCH NECESSARY THE COMMUNITY
THAT HELD A VIGIL.
A NUMBER OF CHURCHES AND
PLACES AROUND TOWN ALLOWED
PIME TO GATHER AND REFLECK ON
WHAT HAPPENED.
THIS COMMUNITY JUST COMING TO
GRIPS WITH THE GRIEF.
I POKE WITH THE MON SINGOR AND
HE SPEPT THE DAY WITH PARTNERS
THAT LOST THEIR CHILDREN.
HE SAID THEY ARE HOLDING UP AS
WELL AS CAN BE EXPECTED AND
SHARING THE JOYFUL MEMORIES
THAT THEY HAD WITH THEIR WHICH
WERE AND IN THE TIME OF ADVENT
AND PEOPLE GOING TO CHURCH AND
PREPARING FOR SO MUCH JOY AND
BIRTH OF CHRIST AND
CELEBRATING CHRISTMAS, HOW DID
PEOPLE COPE WITH THE FACT THAT
IT IS IT CHRISTMAS TIME.
HE SAID THERE ARE 20 BRIGHTER
STARS IN HEN THAN THE LIGHT
NECESSARY NEWTOWN.
THIS COMMUNITY LOST 20
CHILDREN GONE AND PEOPLE JUST
BEGINNING TO COPE AND COMING
TOGETHER.
I RESPONDENT TIME ON MAIN
STREET.
IT IS IT A POP AND MOM SHOP.
AND A WOMAN WHO CUTS
CHILDREN'S HAIR IN TOWN AND
SHE WAS WAITING TO SEE HOW
MANY OF THE KIDS SHE KNOWS
WERE AMONG THE INJURED OR
DEAD.
WE ALSO SPENT TIME IN THE
COMMUNITY IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD
WHERE THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER
LIVED NANCY LANZA HOME WHERE
SHE WAS MURDERED AND SHOT
BEFORE HER SON ADAM TOOK HER
FAMILY CAR ASK HEADED FOR THE
SCHOOL.
AND BEAUTIFUL BIG HOMES AND
ADORABLE NEIGHBORHOOD FILLED
WITH CHRISTMAS LIGHTS AND IT
LOOKED LIKE ANY OTHER
JOY-FILLED NEIGHBORHOOD AT
THIS TIME IN THE HOLIDAYS, BUT
INSTEAD MARKED OFF WITH YELLOW
CRIME TAPE AND WE COULD BARELY
SEE WHERE THE HOME WAS AND TO
WHERE THE SWAT TEEMS AND
AUTHORITIES THAT HAD BEEN
THERE EARLIERING AND SPENT
THEIR TIME EARLIER IN THE DAY.
WE WERE THERE AT THREE O'CLOCK
IN THE AFTERNOON WHEN WAT TEEM
MEMBERS AND INVESTIGATOR IT IS
- INVESTIGATORS STARTED TO
CLEAR OUT AND EARLIER IN THE
DAY THEY FINALLY FOUND OUT
WHERE TO GO TO BEGIN TO LOOK
FOR CLUES AND WHY ADAM LANZA
WOULD HAVE PARTICIPATING IN
THIS.
AND HOW IT COULD HAVE OCCURRED
AND THEY WERE LOOKING FOR
CLUES AND POSSIBLE DANGER.
AND THEY STILL HAVE PIME THEY
ARE KEEPING EYES ON THOSE
THINGS AND DEVASTATED
NEIGHBORS AND CONFUSED
NEIGHBORS IN THE COMMUNITY AND
STATE YOUR NAMELY NOT USED TO
SOMETHING LIKE THIS OCCURRING
IN A NEIGHBORHOOD LIKE
NEWTOWN.
THIS IS IT A PLACE WHERE
PEOPLE MOVE IPERALLY FOR THE
ADORABLE THROW BACK COMMUNITY
AND FOR THAT ESSENCE OF WHAT
EVERYONE WANTS THEIR CHILDREN
TO EXPERIENCE.
SMALL-TOWN FEELING AND WHERE
HUNDREDS AND HUNDREDS OF
PEOPLE WILL SHOW UP AT A
COMMUNITY CHURCH TO GRIEVE AND
WORK AND JOIN TOGETHER TO
REPAIR .
GRET A. >> MOLLY, THANK YOU.
STRETCHING ALL THE WAY FROM
CONNECTICUT TO NEW JERSEY.
THE KILLER'S BROTHER WAS TAKEN
IN FOR QUESTION OR
VOLUNTEERED.
AND HE WAS VOLUNTEERED TO TALK
TO POLICE AND THAT IS WHERE
THEY ARE STANDING BY LIVE.
>> WHAT CAN YOU TELL ME ABOUT
THE BROTHER AND THE
QUESTIONING?
>> WE ARE STANDING IN FRONT OF
HIS HOME.
24 YEAR OLD RYAN LANZA,
BROTHER OF THE ALLEGED SHOOTER
AND I CAN TELL YOU LESS THAN
AN HOUR AGO, POLICE ROLLED UP
THEIR TAPE THAT WAS BLOCK THE
ENTRANCE OF THE BUILDING.
WE HEAR FROM A RELIABLE
FEDERAL SOURCE THAT WHEN
POLICE WERE SURROUNDING THE
AREA EARLIER THIS AFTERNOON.
RYAN AND HIS GIRL FRIEND
SHOWED UP AND THAT'S WHEN THEY
REALIZED EVERYTHING THAT WAS
GOING ON.
AND HE WAS HAND CUFFED AND
TAKEN AWAY AND WE ARE HEAR
ARING FROM THE FBI THAT HOE
AND HIS FATHER WERE RELEASED
AND THEY WERE COOPERATIVE
THROUGHOUT ALL OF THIS.
AND WE ARE HEARING FROM
RESIDENTS HERE THAT ARE
RATTLED BY ALL OF THIS.
THEY SAY THE BOMB SQUAD WAS
RUNNING THROUGH THE HALLWAYS
TODAY.
AND A DAY CARE IN THE AREA WAS
ON LOCK DOWN AND PARENTS WERE
GETTING E-MAILS SAYING DON'T
WORRY ABOUT YOUR KIDS THAT IS
IT WHAT IS GOING O. GRETA,
THEY ARE HAPPY THAT THINGS ARE
CALMING DOWN AND THANKFUL THAT
THEIR KIDS ARE ALL RIGHT.
>> YOU KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT THE
RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN THE
FATHER AND THE SHOOTER OR THE
BROTHER AND THE SHOOTER OR
EVERYTHING THE FATHER AND
MOTHER WHO WAS SHOT TODAY?
>> WE HAVE HEARD A LOT OF
REPORTS AND NOTHING THAT WE
CONFIRMED.
WE HAVE CALLS IN TO THE
FAMILIES, BUT YOU CAN IMAGINE
THEY ARE SAYING THEY NEED TIME
AND NOT TAKING OUR CALLS AT
THE, BUT IT APPEARS THAT SOME
OF THE RELATIONSHIPS HAVE BEEN
SPOTTY AND THE FATHER, AND
MOTHER ARE DIVORCED.
THE FATHER PETER LANZA SINCE
REMARRIED AND LIVES IN
CONNECTICUT AND HE AND THE SON
RYAN ARE ON THE WAY TO
CONNECTICUT.
ALTHOUGH RYAN IS NOT A
SUSPECT, ARE TELLING US THEY
ARE GOING THROUGH HIS COMPUTER
AND RECORDS JUST TO SEE IF
THAT CAN GIVE THEM CLUES ABOUT
ANYTHING AND MAYBE A MOTIVE.
>> THANK YOU .
POLICE FAMILIAR US IT WILL
TAKE DICELET GRUESOME CRUME -
CRIME SCENE.
CHILDREN SLAUGHTERED INSIDE OF
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE SPOKE WITH PAUL VANCE.
>> THANK YOU VERY HAVING US.
>> LIEUTENANT, WE HAVE SEEN SO
MANY GOING BACK TO COLUMBINE
AND YOU NEVER THINK IT IS
GOING TO HAPPEN IN YOUR OWN
COMMUNITY.
>> IT IS IT HORRIFIC AND
TRAGIC AND THE PARENTS SENT
THESE CHILDREN TO BE EDUCATE
NEVER EXPECTED TO NEVER SEE
THEM AGAIN IT IS IT A
HEARTBREAKING TRAG TEE.
>> AND YOU THINK THAT RIGHT
NOW.
YOU HAVEN'T IDENTIFIED ALL OF
THE BODIES FOR THE FAMILIES
HAVE YOU?
>> WE HAVE A PROCESS WHERE WE
HAVE TO POSITIVELY IDENTIFY
EVERYONE AND WE WANT TO DO
THAT AS EXPEDITIOUSLY AS
POSSIBLE WORKING ON THISTHAT
RIGHT NOW IT IS IMPORTANT FOR
THE FAMILIES AND WHY
UNDERSTAND THAT.
>> IMAGINE YOU HAVEN'T GOT
OFFICIAL WORLD AND YOUR CHILD
IS NOT HOME AND SO YOU KNOW
THAT YOUR CHILD WAS ONE OF THE
VICTIMS.
IMAGINE THAT PAIN?
>> IT IS IT UNBELIEVABLE.
IT IS SOMETHING THAT NO ONE
WANT TO BEAR AND IT WAS
HEARTBREAKING TO HAVE TO HEAR
THE PARTNERS TOLD THAT THEIR
CHILDREN WERE NOT COMING HOME.
IT WAS HEART BREAKING FOR THE
LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICERS TO GO
IN AND RESCUE AS MANY PEOPLE
AND ATFERS AND ENCOUNTERED
WHAT THEY DISCOVERED IN THE
LAST TWO CLASSROOMS.
>> WASLETUATION WHERE HE KILL
WOULD AN ENTIRE CLASS IN >> IT
WAS NOT LIKE THAT AND IT ISINE
DIFFICULT TO TALK ABOUT.
SUFFICE TO SAY THERE WERE
DECEASED IN TWO CLASSROOMS AND
HALLWAY AND A HORRIFIC SCENE.
WAS HE TO LAW ENFORCEMENT?
>> WE ARE LOOKING AT THAT.
WE HAVE A STATE POLICE COMMAND
SITUATION AND BROUGHT IN MAJOR
CRIME DETECTIVES AND NEWTOWN
POLICE DETECTIVES WORKING WITH
US AND WE'LL ANSWER THAT
QUESTION AND WE'LL DO AN
EXTENSIVE BACKGROUND AND
ANSWER THE QUESTION ABOUT THE
HISTORY AND HISTORICAL EVENS
THAT THIS YOUNG MAN MAY HAVE
BEEN INVOLVED N. AND WE'LL
LEAVE NO STONE UNTURNED.
>> DID THE SCHOOL KNOW HIM OR
MOTHER COMPLAIN OR WORRIED
ABOUT HIM?
>> THERE WAS NOTHING THAT
SHOWED THAT SOMETHING LIKE
THIS COULD OCCUR .
OUR INVESTIGATORS WILL LOOK AT
ALL OF THAT AND CERTAINLY LOOK
AT THE ADMINISTRATION OF THE
SCHOOL AND FRIENDS AND FAMILY
AND RELATIVES.
AND THIS ISENDLESS AND WE'LL
DO EVERYTHING WE HAVE TO
ANSWER THE QUESTIONS.
>> I DON'T UNDERSTAND AND
CLEAR IT UP FOR ME AND I READ
OR HEARD THAT THE MOTHER WAS
FOUND DEAD AT HER HOME AND
ALSO A TEACHER.
WAS SHE NOT TEACHING OR CALL
IN SICK.
WHY WAS SHE NOT AT SICK?
>> WE HAVEN'T IDENTIFIED
OFFICIALLY ANYONE YET.
I CAN TELL YOU, WE HAVE A
SECONDARY SCENE WITH A
DECEASED FEPLAIL WHO WE
TENTATIVELY IDENTIFIED .
THOSE ARE QUESTIONS WE HAVE
AND WILL HAVE TO ANSWER.
NCAN YOU TELL ME WHETHER THERE
WAS A SUBSTITUTE TEACHER IN
THE CLASS ROM.
>> I DON'T KNOW.
I AM SORRY I DON'T KNOW.
>> MEDICAL EXAMINERS IN WITH
THE CHILDREN AND ADULTINGS.
>> MEDICAL EXAMINERS ARE THERE
WITH THE TEEM IN PLACE.
AND THEY ARE GOING TO WORK
THROUGHOUT THE NIGHT AND DO
WHATEVER THEY NEED TO DO TO
IDENTIFY THE CHILDREN FOR THE
FAMILIES.
>> EVERY TIME I RECOVER THE
STORY, LAW ENFORCEMENT AND
THER ALL PARTNER THEY GO INTO
THESE SCENES AND IT IS JUST
UNTHINKABLE AND UNPEEKABLE.
THEY ALL HAVE KIDS THE AGE OF
THESE CHILDREN MUCH.
>> IT IS IT A VERY SCENE FOR
THEM.
THE LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICERS
WHO INTERESTED THE BUILDING WE
HAVE PROVIDED THEM WITH
COUNSELING AND WE DID THE SAME
FOR THE FAMILY THAT BROUGHT IN
CLERGY .
IT IS IT HARD FOR LAW ENFORCE
MS PERSONNEL AND CERTAINLY
NOTHING LIKE WHAT THE PARTNERS
ARE GOING THROUGH.
>> NO PARENT WANTS TO SEND HIS
CHILD TO SCHOOL WITH A PRISON
AND LOTS OF METAL DETECTORS,
BUT I AM CURIOUS, WAS THE
SECURITY NOT THAT I AM
CONDEMNING IF IT HASN'T.
YOU IT GOES BOTH WAYS.
>> SUFFICE TO SAY THE SCHOOL
WAS VERY SECURE.
AND WHY WILL CERTAINLY
DETERMINE EXACTLY HOW THE
SHOOTER WAS ABLE TO GAIN
ACCESS .
>> SECURE IN A SENSE IF I
TRIED TO GET IN SOMEBODY WOULD
STOP ME AND SOMEBODY WILL LET
ME IN.
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
YOU COULDN'T HAVE GOTTEN IN.
>> GOOD LUCK AND IF IS TOUGH
ON YOU AND ESPECIALLY THE
FAMILIES OF THE DEAD.
THANK YOU, SIR .
OUR LIVE COURAGE CONTINUES IN
A MINUTE.
WE WILL HAVE MORE ON THE LONG
INVESTIGATION ATODAY AND ON
THE RECORD MUCH MORE ALIVE
FROM NEWTOWN, STAY WITH US.
I JUST KNEW WE HAD TO GET IN
THERE AND IT IS IT GOING TO BE
OKAY AND YOU ARE GOING TO BE
ALL RIGHT I PULL WOULD A BOOK
SHELF AND WE WERE BARRICADED
AND DID YOU TELL THEM TO BE
QUIET.
NDID YOU WORRY ABOUT THAT.
>> I TOLD THEM TO BE
ABSOLUTELY QUIET.
BECAUSE I WAS SO AFRAID HE
WOULD COME IN AND HEAR US AND
START SHOOTING THE DOR.
WE HAVE TO BE ABSOLUTELY
QUIET.
AND WE HAVE.
THERE ARE BAD GOYS OUT THERE
NOW.
AND WE NEED TO WAIT FOR THE
GOOD GUYS.
I JUST WANTED US TO BE OKAY.
AND I AM SO SADDENED THRATHERE
ARE PIME IN THE SITUATION THAT
ARE NOT OKAY.
MY HEART GOES OUT TO WHO KNEW
THEM AND WAS PART OF THEIR
LIVES.
I CAN'T IMAGINE.
TRAGICALLY, THEIR DDY
GOT SACKED BY BLACKOUTS.
BUT IT'S OUR TRADITION!
THAT'S ROUGHING
THE CARD HOLDER.
BUT WITH
THE Capital One Venture Card
YOU GET DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE.
[ cheering ]
ANY FLIGHT, ANYTIME.
THE SCOREBOARD DOESN'T LIE.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET? HUT!
I HAVE ME ON MY FANTASY TEAM.
TO TELL REAL PEOPLE ABOUT
OUR NEW 15 UNDER $15 MENU.
OH MY GOODNESS!
OH MY GOSH,
THIS LOOKS AMAZING!
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR NEW MAINE STAYS!
15ENTREES UNDER $15,
SEAFOOD, CHICKEN AND MORE!
OOTHE TILAPIAWITH ROASTEDEGETAB!
I'M ACTUALLY LOOKING AT
THE WO GRILLED CHICKEN
WITH PORTOBELLO WINE SAUCE.
AT PORK CHOP
WAS GREAT!
NO MORE
FAST FOOD FRIDAY'S!
WE'RE GOING TO GO
TO RED LOBSTER.
YEP.
[ Male Announcer ]
COME TRY OUR NEW MENU
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
SALAD, SANDWICHES, AND MORE.
BY SHOWING YOU
THE APARTMENT BUILDING
WHERE THE FIRE WAS.
WHEN THINGS LIKE THIS HAPPEN,
I THINK YOU FIND
A NEW PERSPECTIVE ON LIFE.
RED CROSS PUT US IN A HOTEL
SO WE WERE ABLE
TO STAY TOGETHER.
>> YOU FIND A NEW PERSPECTIVE
AND WE WERE ABLE TO STAY
TOGETHER.
>> WE ARE STRONG.
AND IF WE ALL OVERCAME THAT.
♪
>> WE ARE BACK LIVE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THE PRETTY NEW ENGLAND TOWN
NOW THE SCENE OF ONE OF THE
DEADLIEST SCHOOL SHOOTINGS IN
HISTORY.
ADAM LANZA IS THE KILLER,
FIRST REPORTS IDENTIFIED HIS
BROTHER RYAN LANZA AS THE
KILLER.
HOW DID THAT HAPPEN.
CLAR MOSES JOINS US.
HOW DID IT HAPPEN THAT THERE
WAS CONFUSION AND YOU SPOKE TO
FRENS OF RYAN, HAVE YOU NOT?
>> I DID SPEAK TO FRIENDS OF
RYAN.
THERE WAS A LOT OF CONFUSION
AND THE INTERNET START TOD
PUBLISH RYAN PICTURES AND THEY
CALLED HIM THE KILLER.
AT THAT VERY MOMENT I TALKED
TO SOME OF HIS FRIENDS BY TEXT
AND PHONE AND THEY TOLD ME, I
POKE TO THREE OF HIS FRIENDS
AND THEY HAD SPOKEN TO HIM
BRIEFLY ON BOOK BOOK CHAT OR
BY PHONE AND HE WAS IN FACT AT
WORK AND NOT THE KILLER .
IT WAS PHYSICALLY IMPOSSIBLE
FOR HIM TO BE IN NEWTOWN WHILE
HE WAS AT WORK AND TALKING ON
THE PHONE TO HIS FRIENDS.
>> BUT YOU KNOW.
>> YES?
>> DO YOU KNOW IF HIS FRIENDS,
DID ANY OF RYAN'S FRIEND EVER
MET ADAM?
>> NOT THE ONES THAT I SPOKE
TO.
THEY KNEW HE HAD A BROTHER AND
THAT IS ABOUT THE EXTENT OF
THEIR KNOWLEDGE.
THEY HAD BRIEF CONVERSATIONS
WITH HIM TODAY AS YOU CAN
IMAGINE IT WAS A CRAZY DAY FOR
HIM SO THEY JUST HAD A FEW
MINUTES AND THEY KNEW HE HAD A
BROTHER BUT NONE OF THEM
SEEMED TO KNOW ADAM.
>> DID THEY KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT ADAM, DID RYAN EVER PEEK
ABOUT ADAM OR DESCRIBE UNUSUAL
OR NOT UNUSUAL OR A
RELATIONSHIP WITH HIM OR
ANYTHING?
>> THERE IS VERY LITTLE
KNOWLEDGE ABOUT THAT.
ONE OF HIS FRIENDS DID TELL ME
IN FACT, HE HAD A BROTHER AND
THAT HE MIGHT HAVE BEEN A
LITTLE CHALLENGED, AND
DEVELOPMENTALLY CHALLENGED BUT
THAT IS ALL OF THE
INFORMATION.
OTHER INFORMATION IS VERY
SPARSE.
HIS FRIENDS DIDN'T SEEM TO
KNOW HIS FAMILY OR AT LEAST
THEY DIDN'T MENTION THAT
TODAY.
YOU DON'T HAVE ANY MORE
INFORMATION.
>> I AM SORRY ONE MORE TIME
GRETA?
NBEYOND MENTALLY CHALLENGED
YOU DON'T KNOW ANYTHING MORE
ABOUT ADAM?
NNOT ABOUT ADAM, NOT ABOUT
ADAM.
WE HEARD EARLIER TODAY THAT
ADAM COULD HAVE HAD RYAN'S
IDENTIFICATION ON HIM.
RYAN TOLD ONE OF HIS FRIENDS
THAT THE CONFUSION AROSE THAT
WAY AND IT WAS PROBABLY ADAM
RATHER THAN HIMSELF.
BUT OTHER THAN THAT THERE WAS
LITTLE INFORMATION ABOUT ADAM
HERE IN HOBOKEN.
>> THANK YOU.
>> COMING UP.
IT TOOK ONLY MINUTES FOR THE
KILLER TO GUN DOWN 20 CHILDREN
AND 6 ADULTS.
OUR LIVE COVERAGE IN
CONNECTICUT CONTINUES, THAT'S
NEXT .
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
>> UNTHINKABLE TRAGEDY
UNFOLDED.
BREAKING NEWS TO TELL YOU
RIGHT NOW.
THERE ARE REPORTS OF A SCHOOL
SHOOT NOTHING NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THIS IS IT IN THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> STATE POLICE RESPONDED TO
THE REPORT OF THE A SHOOTING
IN SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
WHICH WE NOW UNDERSTAND IS
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADE.
>> THIS IS REPORTED.
APE DISPATCHER SAID THAT ONE
TEACHER HAS BEEN TRANSPORTED
TO A NEARBY HOSPITAL IN
DANBURY WITH A GUNSHOT WOUND.
>> AHEAD OF HIM IT IS
DIFFICULT TO SEE THE WAT THEM
THAT WAS RESPONDING.
THOSE VEHICLES RACED FROM
NEWTOWN FROM ALL OVER THE
STATE OF CONNECTICUT.
>> WE HEARD NUMEROUS REPORTS
THAT ONE GUNMAN MAYBE TWO.
AND TWO REPORTS SAID THAT ONE
GUNMAN MAY BE DEAD .
IT IS A FAST-MOVE FLUID
SITUATION IN THE SCHOOL .
>> I THINK IT IS IT IMPORTANT
ON A DAY LIKE TODAY TO VIEW
THIS AS I KNOW THE PRESIDENT,
AS A FATHER DOES AND I THE
FATHER AND OTHERS WHO PARTNERS
CERTAIN LIE DO, WHICH -- OTHER
PARENTS CERTAINLY DO.
FEELING ENORMOUS SYMPATHY FOR
THE FAMILIES THAT ARE
AFFECTED.
AND DO EVERYTHING WE CAN.
>>S ARE TELLING FOX NUSE THAT
26 PEOPLE ARE DEAD AT THIS
TIME AND EIGHT ADULTS
INCLUDING THE SHOOTER AND 18
CHILDREN .
>> IS A GUN SHOT AND SO THEY
ARE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHAT
HAPPENED .
WE TELL THEM WHAT HAPPENED IN
THE DEAT AS AND IT MAKES IT
MUCH WORSE.
>> THE SHOOTER MAY A YOUNG MAN
20 YEARS OLD AND HE MAY LIVE
IN NEW JERSEY AND THERE MAY
HAVE BEEN A SEPARATE SITUATION
THERE, A CRIME SCENE WHERE
THEY KICKED DOWN THE DOOR OF
THAT PERSON'S HOME.
WE ARE TRYING TO CONFIRM THAT.
WE DON'T KNOW THE IDENTITY OF
THE GUNMAN .
>> THERE WERE FATAILITIES AT
THE SCENE AND BOTH STUDENT AND
STAFF.
THERE IS NO INFORMATION
RELATIVE TO THAT AND RELEASED
AT THAT TIME AND WE MAKE A
COMPLETE AND PROPER
NOTIFICATION.
>> IT IS SHEER TERROR AND A
SENSE OF IMMEDIATE URGENCY AND
YOU KNOW TO GET TO YOUR CHILD
AND TO BE THERE TO PROTECT
THEM.
>> THE PRESIDENT WILL MAKE
REMARKS ABOUT THE SHOOTING
TODAY.
WE'LL TAKE A LISTEN.
>> THIS AFTERNOON, I SPOKE
WITH GOVERNOR MALOY AND FBI
DIRECTOR MUELLER.
I OFFERED OUR CONDOLENCES ON
BEHALF OF THE NATION AND MADE
IT CLEAR HE WILL HAVE EVERY
SINGLE RESOURCE HE NEEDS TO
INVESTIGATE THE HEINOUS CRIME
AND CARE FOR THE VICTIMS AND
COUNSEL THEIR FAMILIES.
>> THERE WERE FATALITIES.
18 CHILDREN PRONOUNCED DEAD AT
THE SCHOOL.
TWO TRANSPORTED TO AREA HELPS
AND PRONOUNCED DEAD AT AREA
HOSPITALS AND SIX ADULTS
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCENE
OF THE SCHOOL.
>> THIS HAPPENED OVER SIX
HOURS AGO THERE IS IT A LOT OF
EVIDENCE BEING PROCESSED AND
THE CRIME SCENE IS ACTIVE AND
OTHER SCENES ARE NOW BEING
INVESTIGATED INCLUDING
APPARENTLY THE HOME OF THE
SHOOTER'S MOTHER IN NEWTOWN
WHERE AN ADULT BODY WAS FOUND
AND OTHER RESIDENCE IN NEW
JERSEY.
THERE ARE CONFLICTING REPORTS
OF THE STATUS OF THE SHOOTER'S
FATHER AND CONFLICTING
REPORTOS THE SHOOTER HIMSELF.
>> THE MAJORITY THAT DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5-10 YEARS OLD .
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS AND GRADUATIONS AND
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN .
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS, MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES TO HELPING
OUR CHILDREN FULFILL THE
DREAMS.
SO OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN
TODAY, FOR THE PARTNERS AND
GRANDPARENTS, SISTERS AND
BROTHERS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN, AND FOR THE FAMILIES
OF THE ADULTS THAT WERE LOST.
>> THE SHEER TERROR AND YOUNG
CHILDREN AND PARTNERS AND
TEACHERS ALL WITNESSING THE
TRAGEDY AND VIOLENCE.
NIT DOESN'T SEEM REAL.
IT DOESN'T SEEM POSSIBLE.
>> IT IS NO WORDS.
IT IS IT SHEER TERROR AND A
SENSE OF IMMEDIATE URGEENCY.
AND YOU KNOW TO GET TO YOUR
CHILD AND TO BE THERE TO
PROTECT THEM.
NI HAVE AN EMERGENCY PHONE
CALL THAT THERE WAS A SHOOTING
AND THEY SAY WHERE AND THE
SCHOOLS ARE ON LOCK DOWN AND
IMMEDIATELY AFTER THAT I GOT A
TEST FROM AP THAT THERE WAS A
SHOOTING IN THE SCHOOL SANDY
HOOK.
AND SO I LEFT AND WENT TO THE
SCHOOL.
THERE WERE HISERICAL MOMS THEY
KNEW AND I SAID WHAT IS GOING
ON.
SHE SAID THE PRINCIPAL IS DEAD
AND THE CHILDREN CAME OUT WITH
BLOOD.
>> WE ARE COPING AND TRYING TO
FIND OUT WHAT IS GOING ON.
IT IS IT NERVE RACKING.
WE HAVE MORE CARS PULLING IN.
AND HOW MANY INJURED.
>> SHE WAS IN A SMALL READING
GROUP, AND THEY STARTED TO
HEARING I GUESS BANGS.
AND HER TEACHER WHICH I AM SO
GRATEFUL FOR.
IT WAS A SMALL GROUP.
THEY RUSHED THE KIDS INTO THE
BATHROOM AND THEY LOCKED THE
DOOR AND THEY JUST TOLD THE
CHILDREN IT WAS HAMMERING AND
TRIED TO KEEP THEM CALM.
AND THE NEXT THING I KNOW,
BECAUSE IT IS HARD TO GET THE
COMPLETE STORY, THE NEXT THING
I KNOW IS THAT THE POLICE CAME
AND THEY WERE KNOCKING ON THE
DOOR TO BE LET OUT.
WHEN THEY WERE SHE SAW GLASS
AND BLOOD AND ONE CHILD
COVERED IN BLOOD BUT I
UNDERSTAND THAT CHILD IS SAFE
.
>> SHE WAS TALKING ABOUT HOW
THE WHILE SHE WAS WALKING DOWN
THE HALLWAY, THE POLICE TOLD
THEM TO CLOSE THEIR EYES.
OBVIOUSLY IT WAS A SENSITIVE
SCENE AND SHE SAID SHE HEARD
GUN SHOTS AND ACTUALLY WHAT
SHE TOLD ME WAS IN THE
BEGINNING, THE INTERCOM CAME
ON AND SHE HEARD A SCREAM ON
THE INTERCOM AND IT WENT
IMMEDIATELY OFF.
I AM NOT SURE AT THE SPECIFICS
OF THE LOCK DOWN.
>> NOTHING MAKES SENSE LIKE
THIS.
NO IT DOESN'T.
OUR HEARTS ARE WITH EVERYBODY.
EVERY PARENT AND MOTHER AND
FATHER AND GRAND FATHER AND
MOTHER AND SISTER AND BROTHER
FOR ALL OF THE CHILDREN.
>> SHE SEEMED TO BE DOING
OKAY.
BUT A COUPLE OF FRIENDS WE
HAVEN'T GOTTEN IN TOUCH WITH.
WE HOPE THAT EVERYTHING IS
OKAY WITH THEM.
NCOMING UP MORE LIVE COVERAGE
FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT AND
WHY THE PLICE ARE IN THE
SCHOOL.
DETECTIVE MARK FUR MAN IS
HERE, NEXT.
♪
[ engine revs ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THE MERCEDES-BENZ WINTER EVENT
IS BACK,
WITH THE PERFECT VEHICLE
THAT'S JUST RIGHT FOR YOU,
NO MATTER WHICH LIST YOU'RE ON.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
ML350 FOR $599 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
SINCE AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL
WAS FOUNDED BACK IN 1894,
THEY'VE BEEN COMMITTED
TO PUTTING CLIENTS FIRST.
HELPING GENERATIONS
THROUGH TOUGH TIMES.
GOOD TIMES.
NEVER TAKING A BAILOUT.
THERE WHEN YOU NEED THEM.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
OVER THE CENTURIES.
THE STRENGTH OF
A GLOBAL FINANCIAL LEADER.
THE HEART OF
A ONE-TO-ONE RELATIONSHIP.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Sharable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
I HAD[ Designer ]EELING
ENOUGH OF JUST COVERING UP
MY MODERATE TO SEVERE
PLAQUE PSORIASIS.
I DECIDED ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
♪
[ Spa Lady ]
I STARTED ENBREL.
IT'S CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO PROVIDE CLEARER SKIN.
[ RV Guy ] ENBREL MAY NOT WORK
FOR EVERYONE --
AND MAY NOT CLEAR YOU
COMPLETELY,
BUT FOR MANY, IT GETS SKIN
CLEARER FAST, WITHIN 2 MONTHS,
AND KEEPS IT CLEARER
UP TO 9 MONTHS.
[ Male Announcer ]
BECAUSE ENBREL®, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL,
EVENTS INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS, LYMPHOMA,
OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING ENBREL,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START ENBREL IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON ENBREL, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING,
OR PALENESS.
IF YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH, ASK
YOUR DERMATOLOGIST ABOUT ENBREL.
>> TONIGHT THE INVESTIGATION
IN THE CONNECTICUT MASS
SHOOTING IS ONLY BEGINNING.
THE HOMICIDE DETECTIVE MARK
FURMAN JOINS US.
>> GOOD EVENING.
>> MARK, YOU AND I GO BACK A
LONG TIME TALKING ABOUT ALL OF
THESE CASES.
THIS ONE TONIGHT, RIGHT NOW AS
WE TALK.
THE EXAMINER INSIDE OF
THAT CLASSROOM, AND BODIES
STILL IN THE CLASSROOM AND
TRYING TO DETERMINE IDEPTITY.
I CAN ONLY IMAGINE HOW
DIFFICULT IT IS FOR THE POLICE
AND MEDICAL EXAMINER AND
FAMILIES AND EVERYTHING.
THIS HAS TO BE DONE, DOESN'T
IT?
>> IT DOES HAVE TO BE DONE,
GRETA AND UNFORTUNATELY, I CAN
IMAGINE WHAT IT LOOKS LIKE AND
YOU TRY TO PUT THAT OUT OF
YOUR MIND.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER AND
FORENSIC PERSONNEL HAVE TO
BLUE PRIPT THE ROOM WHERE EACH
AND EVERY PERSON IS.
ALL EVIDENCE HAS TO BE
PHOTOGRAPHED BEFORE IT IS
DISTURBED AND YOU HAVE TO
NUMBER AND THE POSITIONS OF
EACH BODY.
EACH BODY HAS TO BE PROCESSED
AND EXAMINED BY THE CORONER
AND FORENSICALLY AND
DOCUMENTED AND EVIDENCE
COLLECTED AND THEN, AND ONLY
THEN CAN YOU REMOVE EACH BODY
ONE AT A TIME.
>> YOU KNOW, I THINK OF THE
FAMILIES TONIGHT.
THEY HAVEN'T GOT KNOW OFFICIAL
WORD THEIR CHILD IS DEAD OR A
LOVED ONE OR WIFE OR MOTHER.
BUT IF YOU ARE SITTING AT HOME
AND YOU ARE EXPECTING YOUR
CHILD TO BE HOME OR EXPECTED
YOUR WIFE OR MOTHER OR FATHER
TO BE HOME AND THAT PERSON
HASN'T SHOWN UP.
YOU OBVIOUSLY KNOW THAT YOU
ARE -- YOUR FAMILY MEMBER WAS
A VICTIM AND A LOT OF PEOPLE
ARE THINKING WHY IN THE WORLD
GOING ON.
WE KNOW WHO THE SHOOTER IS.
HE SHOT HIMSELF IN THE HEAD
AND THERE IS IT A RISK OF A
CO-DEFENDANT OR SOMEONE WHO
HELPED HIM AND YOU WILL HAVE
TO PUT A CASE TOGETHER; IS
THAT WHY THEY DO THIS?
>> YOU HAVE TO DOCUMENT IT,
BECAUSE IT IS WHAT YOU NEED TO
DO TO REALLY CREATE A HISTORY
OF THE INSTENT.
FOR LEGAL PURPOSES AND
CERTAINLY THERE COULD BE CIVIL
ACTIONS IF THERE IS NOT
CRIMINAL.
YOU HAVE TO REMEMBER THAT THIS
SUSPECT WAS DESCRIBED AS
SOMEONE WHO MIGHT HAVE MENTAL
PROBLEMS AND INCAPACITY AS FAR
AS HIS MENTAL STATE HE COULD
HAVE BEEN FORMULATED BY
SOMEONE ELSE AND GUIDED AND
PROVIDED WITH INFORMATION AND
A CONSPIRACY, YOU KNOW.
IT IS REALLY WHAT I AM TALKING
ABOUT AND SOMEBODY COULD HAVE
PUT HIM UP AND GAVE HIM
INFORMATION AND COMPLETED THE
CONSPIRACY.
AND THEN YOU WOULD NEED TO
PROSECUTE THAT INDIVIDUAL.
SO IT NEEDS TO BE DONE BECAUSE
THIS EARLY IN THE
INVESTIGATION, YOU COUNTY
DON'T KNOW -- WHAT YOU HAVE
EXCEPT FOR THE VICTIMS.
>> WE ARE GETTING A LITTLE BIT
OF AN IDEA WHO HE WAS.
AND THE NEW YORK TIMES AND
REPORTING ABOUT HOW SOCIALLY
ACWARD HE HIGH SCHOOL.
AND FEW FREPPEDS AND HE DIDN'T
CENTER A BOOK BOOK -- FACE
BOOK PAGE WE ARE GETTING A
GLIMPSE OF HIM TONIGHT .
BUT THE DETECTIVES.
THEY HAVE TO DIG DEEPER, ARE
THEY NOT?
>> THEY ARE GOING TO DIG
DEEPER FOR WEEKS AND MAYBE
LONGER THAN THAT.
THEY WILL DO AN AUTOPSY ON HIS
MIND AND HIS LIFE AS WELL AS
HIS BODY.
THEY ARE GOING TO FIGURE OUT
WHO HE WAS TALKING TO AND WHAT
HIGH WAS SAYING AND TALK TO
FRIENDS AND FAMILY AND ANYBODY
ON THE COMPUTER AND WEB SITES
AND ANYTHING HE PUT OUT OR
WROTE.
ANYTHING THAT HE THREATENED.
THEY ARE GOING TO FIND OUT
JUST EXACTLY HOW MANY FLAGS
THERE WERE AND THAT IS REALLY
ONLY WAY TO GO BACK WARDS AND
TRY TO PREVENT AN INCIDENT IS
TO CONTROL THE INDIVIDUAL WITH
THE IDEA AND MOTIVATION TO DO
AS HEINOUS AS THIS.
NDO YOU EVER GET USED TO THE
INVESTIGATION .
20 CHILDREN.
THEY ARE LIKE FIVE OR 10 YEARS
OLD.
IT SEEMS LIKE THE WORST OF THE
WORST.
AND AS A DETECTIVE, DO YOU
EVER, CAN YOU DO THIS?
AND HOW DO YOU GO THROUGH
THYSELF THINGS?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, THERE IS NO
WAY THAT ANYBODY CAN PREPARE
THEMSELVES FOR A CHILD'S
HOMICIDE.
JUST IN THE SINGULAR SENSE.
THIS, THE AMOUNT OF
RECOMMEND'RE VICTIMS AND THEIR
AGE IS BEYOND OVERWHELMING.
AND I AM SURE THAT YOU KNOW,
DETECTIVES AND FORENSIC
PERSONNEL.
THEY HAVE TO DETACH THEMSELVES
FOR THAT PERIOD OF TIME TO DO
THEIR JOB.
THIS IS IT A HORRIFIC SCENE
AND A HORRIFIC CRIME THAT NO
ONE WILL GET OVER AND NO ONE
SEEING THE SCENE WILL BE QUITE
THE SAME.
>> MARK, THANK YOU FOR JOINING
US TONIGHT.
>> STRAIGHT AHEAD, YOU WILL
HEAR THE CHILLING RADIO CALLS
AS POLICE LEARNED ABOUT THE
MASS SHOOTING, THAT'S NEXT.
>>.
>>
[ woman ] WE KNEW IT WAS GONNA
BE BAD, BUT NEVER LIKE THIS.
THE RED CROSS WAS DOWN HERE
ALL THE TIME.
[ man ]
THEY'VE GIVEN US A LOT OF HEART.
IN TIMES OF NEED, THEY'RE THERE.
♪
[ Kerry ] MY DAD WAS WATCHING
HIS HOUSE BURN.
HE TURNED AROUND,
AND ALL OF A SUDDEN, THERWAS
THIS GUY STANDING THERE
FROM THE RED CROSS.
AT A POINT WHERE I HAD
JUST LOST EVERYTHING,
THE IDEA THAT THERE WAS
SOMEONE THERE...
THAT'S AN AMAZING THING.
♪
LOTS OF PREPAID CARDS COME
PRE-ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.EMS.NG.
INTRODUCING CHASE LIQUID.
THE RELOADABLE CARD
WITH NO-FEE RELOADS
AND WITHDRAWALS AT CHASE ATMS.
AND NO HEADACHES,
HASSLES OR CONFUSION.
ALL FOR ONE FLAT MONTHLY FEE.
GET RID OF PREPAID PROBLEMS.
GET CHASE LIQUID.
>> GRETA: THIS SCHOOL MASSACRE
SHOCKING EVEN TOCHL PEER YENSED
POLICE OFFICERS.
WE HAVE THE CHILLING RADIO
CALLS AS POLICE FIRST LEARNED
ABOUT THE SLOOT SHOOTHING
SPREE.
LISTEN TO THIS.
>> CALLERS INDICATING SHE
THINKS SOMEONE IS SHOOTING IN
THE BUILDING.
THE ANSWER I!,óç... THE ANSWER S
FRONT GLASS HAS BEEN -- THEY'RE
UNSURE WHY.
THE INDIVIDUAL I HAVE ON THE
PHONE IS CONTINUING TO HEAR
WHAT YOU BELIEVES TO BE
GUNFIRE.
>> AND RIGHT.
RIGHT.
>> OTHER UNITS.
>> THE SHOOTING APPEARS TO
HAVE STOPPED.
THE SCHOOL IS IN LOCK DOWN.
>> ROGER.
>> REPORTS THE TEACHER SAW TWO
RUNNING PAST THE BUILDING PAST
THE GYM, WHICH WOULD BE REAR,
I THINK, NEAR THE SHOOTING.
>> YOUR REQUESTED TO STAY.
I WILL NEED TWO AMBULANCES AT
THIS TIME.
>> JUST RECEIVED A CALL.
WE HAVE ONE IN ROOM ONE WHODdl
RECEIVED A SHOT TO THE FOOT.
OTHER INJURIES AT THIS TIME.
>> OKAY.
BODIES HERE.
>> I THINK IS THAT AN EMF?I#
>> AT THE... DRIVEWAY.
BETWEEN THE FIRE HYDRANT.
>> IS THERE ANYONE?
>> WE'VE GOT ONE SUSPECT DOWN.
BE ADVISED WE HAVE MULTIPLE
WEAPONS INCLUDING LONG RIFLES
AND SHOTGUNS.
WE NEED OFFICERS HERE.
ASAP.
>> WE JUST HAD A CASE BROUGHT
TO US BY A POLICE OFFICER.
>> WOULD YOU CONTACT A COUPLE
OF OUR OFFICERS TO MAN THE
BACK HALL SO WE CAN PUT PEOPLE
INSIDE OF THERE?
>> ONE PATIENT TRANSPORTED TO
THE HOSPITAL.
>> ANOTHER VEHICLE NOT SECURE.
>> NOW 401, 444 ROUTE.
>> MAKE CONTACT WITH THE
COMMANDING OFFICER AT THE
SCENE JUST TO ENSURE THAT THE
AREA YOU'RE GOING INTO HAVE
BEEN CLEARED.
>> OKAY.
WHO IS THE COMMANDING OFFICER
HERE?
>> OFFICER IN THE BACK.
>> ROGER.
>> IT'S OVER BEHIND.
ROGER THERE.
>> ROGER.
>> JERSEY PLACE.
A COUPLE OCCUPANTS.
NOT SURE WHERE I GOT CUTOFF ON
THE CALLER.
>> THIS IS STILL AN ACTIVE
SCENE.
KEEP THE AREA CLEAN.
>> WE'RE INBOUND IN THAT
LOCATION WITH ER SUPPORT.
IS THERE A LINK UP POINT?
>> ROGER.
CLOSET IN THE KITCHEN.
THEY HAVE SOME VICTIMS.
LET US KNOW, WE'LL CALL THE
NUMBER SO THEY'LL KNOW YOU'RE
COMING.
>> ONE OF THE PLACES IS THE
KITCHEN.
THERE IS A TEACHER IN THERE.
>> THE CAR RENTAL, LANE, NEW
JERSEY.
>> THERE IS A GUY ON THE END
OF THE ROAD.
KEEP THE ROAD CLEAR, WE NEED
TO GET EMF OUT OF HERE, KEEP
IT HERE.
>> NEWTOWN OFFICERS AT THE
SCENE.
THE SCENE SCENE IS NOT ACTIVE,
NOT ACTIVE AT THIS TIME.
>> GRETA: STRAIGHT AHEAD ONE
MURDER VICTIM IS THE SCHOOL
PRINCIPAL.
SHE TURNED ON THE P.A.SYSTEM
AS EVENTS WERE UNFOLDING.
YOU'LL HEAR WHAT HAPPENED AS A
RESULT, THAT IS NEXT.
Music is a universal language.
But when I was in an accident...
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
Information on my phone.
Connection to doctors who
get where I'm from.
And tools to estimate what
my care may cost.
So I never missed a beat.
We're more than 78,000
people looking out for
more than 70
million Americans.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.
TO THE BEST VACATION
SP(ALL) THE GULF!
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHICH OF
OUR GREAT STATES FOLKS VISIT.
MISSISSIPPI,
ALABAM
LOUISIANA
OR FLORIDA,
THEY'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
SHAUL, YOUR ALABAMA
HOSPITALITY IS INCREDIBLE.
THANKS, KAREN.
LOVE YOUR MISSISSIPPI OUTDOORS.
I VOTE FOR YOUR
FLORIDA BEACHES, DAWN.
BILL, THIS LOUISIANA
SEAFOOD IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR ON THE GULF,
WE'VE DECIDED TO PUT
ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
NOW IS THE PERFECT TIME TO
VISIT ANYONE OF OUR STATES.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE, GO FISHING
OR JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
WE'VE GOT COASTLINE TO EXPLORE
AND WILDLIFE TO PHOTOGRAPH.
AND THERE'S WORLD CLASS DINING
WITH OUR WORLD FAMOUS SEAFOOD.
SO FOR A GREAT VACATION
THIS YEAR, COME TO THE GULF.
ITS ALL FABULOUS BUT
I GIVE FLORIDA THE EDGE.
RIGHT AFTER MISSISSIPPI.
YOU MEAN ALABAMA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
THIS INVITATION IS
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP
AND ALL OF US WHO
CALL THE GULF HOME.
>> GRETA: 20 SMALL CHILDREN,
SIX ADULTS MASSACRED IN AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
ONE OF THEM, THE SCHOOL PRANCE
PAL.
BUT BEFORE SHE WAS GUNNED DOWN
SHE TURNED ON TD PUBLIC
ADDRESS SYSTEM.
THAT MAY HAVE SAVED LIVES.
GARY, NICE TO SEE YOU.
>> THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
>> YOU SPOKE TO THE NIECE OF
THE PRINCIPAL.
>> YES.
ON A CONFERENCE CALL WITH ONE
OF MY EDITORS.
>> GRETA: WHAT DID SHE SAY?
>> SHE RELATED JUST A
THOUGHTFUL, BEAUTIFUL PERSON
HER AUNT WAS.
SHE SHARED A STORY SHE'DD
HEARD HOW HER AUNT SAVED LIVES
BY PUSHING FOR FOLKS BACK INTO
THE CONFERENCE ROOM.
AND HITTING THE P.A.TO HEAR
WHAT IS GOING ON TO GET
SOMETIME TO GET INTO A SAFE
PLACE.
>> GRETA: SHOOTING GOING
THROUGHOUT THE SCHOOL?
THEY REACHED THE WHOLE SCHOOL?
>> I FOUND INFORMATION WE'VE
HAD CONFIRMED, IT'S A STORY
THAT THE RELATIVE HAS RELAYED
TO US.
SO WE HAVEN'T CONFIRMED THAT
WITH OFFICIAL SOURCES.
BUT IT WAS A STORY THAT THE
RELATIVE, THE NIECE OF THE
PRINCIPAL SHARED WITH US.
>> GRETA: IT'S A TERRIBLE
STORY.
TERRIBLE FOR THE COMMUNITY.
YOU LIVE HERE, GREW UP HERE.
>> YES.
I ARE HAVE FAMILY IN NEWTOWN.
AND IT'S -- IT'S JUST
DEVASTATING.
YOU KNOW?
NO ONE COULD HAVE EVER
IMAGINED SOMETHING LIKE THIS
WOULD HAPPEN ANYWHERE, OR
HERE.
AND THERE IS A REAL SADNESS,