YOU WANT TO SEE IT, IT'S A BIG
THING.
BIG DEAL TONIGHT.
SO CHECK IT OUT THERE.
ALSO, WE WOULD LIKE FOR TO YOU
SPOUT OFF ABOUT THE FACTOR FROM
ANYWHERE IN THE WORLD.
NAME AND TOWN IF YOU WISH TO
OPINE.
WORD OF THE DAY, DO NOT BE A
MISCREANT.
WHO LOVES THAT WORD?
DO KNOW BE A MISCREANT WHEN
WRITING TO THE FACTOR.
THANKS FOR WATCHING.
I AM BILL O'REILLY.
PLEASE, ALWAYS REMEMBER THAT THE
SPIN STOPS RIGHT HERE BECAUSE WE
ARE DEFINITELY LOOKING OUT FOR
YOU.
>> SEAN: THIS IS A FOX NEWS
ALER.
SUSAN RICE, THE U.S. AMBASSADOR
TO THE UNITED NATIONS WERE YOU
HER NAME FROM CONSIDERATION TO
BE THE NEXT SECRETARY OF STATE
IN A LETTER TO PRESIDENT OBAMA,
RICE WROTE, QUOTE, I AM FULLY
CONFIDENT THAT I COULD SERVE OUR
COUNTRY ABLY AND EFFECTIVELY IN
THAT ROLE.
HOWEVER, IF NOMINATED, I AM NOW
CONVINCED THAT THE CONFIRMATION
PROCESS WOULD BE LEATH --
LENGTHY, DISRUPTIVE AND COSTLY
TO YOU AND OUR MOST PRESSING
NATIONAL AND INTERNATIONAL
PRIORITIES AND THAT IS NOT WORTH
IT TO OUR COUNTRY.
THIS COMES IN THE WAKE OF
REPUBLICAN LAWMAKERS, EXPRESSING
OPPOSITION TO HER POTENTIAL
NOMINATION BECAUSE OF COMMENTS
SHOW MADE FIVE DAYS AFTER FOUR
AMERICANS WERE KILLED IN A
BLATANT TERRORIST ATTACK IN
BENGHAZI IN SEPTEMBER.
AMBASSADOR RICE BLAMED ALL THE
VIOLENCE ON A youtube VIDEO,
WHEN ALL THE EVIDENCE SHOWED
THIS WAS ABSOLUTELY NOT TROUGH.
PRESIDENT OBAMA RESPONDED TO THE
LETTER EARLIER TODAY AND SAID
THE ATTACKS ON AMBASSADOR RICE
IN RECENT WEEKS HAVE BEEN BOTH
UNFAIR AND MISLEADING.
BUT GET THIS, IN TYPICAL
FASHION, NBC NEWS JUMPED IN TO
RICE'S DEFENSE AND CONTINUED
THEIR FALSE NARRATIVE THAT ANY
CRITICISM OF HER IS NOT ROOTED
IN HER FALSE TESTIMONY, BUT
RACISM, OTHER DOG WHISTLE.
WATCH THIS.
>> I THINK THAT THIS HAD BECOME
SORT OF AN IMPOSSIBLE CHALLENGE
FOR HER TO BE CONFIRMED, THAT
SHE REALIZED THAT, THE WHITE
HOUSE REALIZED IT AS WELL.
I THINK THEY KNOW THEY ARE ON
GOOD POLITICAL, SOLID GROUND, AS
YOU WERE POINTING OUT.
THIS IS NOT GOING TO HELP
REPUBLICANS AT ALL, THE FACT
THAT A WOMAN AND A WOMAN OF
COLOR HAS BEEN FORCED OUT OF A
CONFIRMATION PROCESS BEFORE SHE
WAS NOMINATED.
JOINING ME WITH REACTION, FORMER
SPEAKER OF THE HOUSE, NEWT
GINGRICH.
>> I AM DOING VERY WELL.
I COULDN'T HELP BUT SMILE AT THE
ABSURDITY.
THE REPUBLICAN PARTY DID
NOMINATE COLIN POWELL, WHO
BECAME THE SECRETARY OF STATE.
THEY DID NOMINATE CONDOLEEZZA
RICE, WHO BECAME SECRETARY OF
STATE.
IT WOULD BE HARD TO SAY THAT THE
SENATOR WHO IS HAD PROBLEMS WERE
DOING SO FOR EITHER RACIAL OR
SEXUAL REASONS.
THEY HAVE PROVEN THE WILLINGNESS
TO WORK WITH AFRICAN-AMERICANS
OF BOTH MALE AND FEMALE.
I THINK IT WOULD NOT BE A BAD
IDEA FOR PRESIDENT OBOTTOMING --
OBAMA TO SEE IF COLIN POWELL
WOULD COME OUT OF RETIREMENT AND
THAT MIB A BIPARTISAN STEP TO
MOVE US IN A DIRECTION OF A
DIFFERENT KIND OF DIALOGUE THAT
WE ARE GOING TO GET, IF WE STAY
WITH LEFT-WING POLICIES?
IT'S INTERESTING.
THE EVIDENCE WAS OVERWHELMING.
IT WAS INCONVERTIBLE IN THIS
PARTICULAR CASE, BUT
DEMOCRATS -- THE CAMPAIGN NEVER
STOPS.
THERE IS NO TIME FOR GOVERNING
HERE, WHATSOEVER.
IT SEEMS THAT THEY WANT TO
HUMILIATE, CRUSH, DIVIDE AND
HURT THE REPUBLICAN PARTY.
AM I WRONG, AS I OBSERVE THE
FISCAL CLIFF AND THE ATTACKS
THAT NEVER END -- WAR ON WOMEN,
NEVER ENDS?
>> YOU KNOW, I WAS A BIG FAN AND
VERY, VERY IMPRESSED WITH COACH
WOOTEN'S USE OF THE FULL-COURT
PRESS AT UCLA.
ONE OF THE MOST REMARKABLE
BASKETBALL DINE SEE -- DYNASTIEN
HISTORY, IF YOU ARE RUNNING
AGAINST A FULL-COURT PRESS, YOU
BETTER RUN AGAINST THE
FULL-COURT PRESS.
A CHICAGO-STYLE MACHINE IS
TRYING TO ESTABLISH A PERMANENT
24-HOUR-A-DAY, 365-DAY-A-YEAR
CAMPAIGN.
WE BETTER LEARN HOW IT COPE WITH
AND HOW TO BE INVOLVED WITH IT.
THE FACT IS, IN THE CASE OF
AMBASSADOR RICE, SHE IS THE
PERSON WHO HAS A GRIEVANCE WITH
THE PRESIDENT.
SHE WAS SENT OUT BY THE
PRESIDENT TO SAY THINGS THAT
WERE FALSE.
SHE WAS USED FOR FIVE SHOWS IN
ONE SUNDAY TO TELL THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE SOMETHING THAT WAS NOT
TRUE.
AND I THINK IF SHE HAS A
COMPLAINT WITH ANYBODY, IT OUGHT
TO BE WITH PRESIDENT OBAMA WHO
SENT HER OUT THERE, USING HER
POLITICALLY, EVEN THOUGH SHE WAS
THE U.N. AMBASSADOR.
>> SEAN: YOU ALWAYS HAVE AN
INTERESTING TAKE ON THE EVENTS
OF THE DAY.
WE HAVE ALL OF THESE INCIDENCE
OF VIOLENCE -- UP ON, WE SEE THE
LEFT AND THE G-8 AND G-20
SUMMITS.
WE SEE STEVEN CROWDER, PUNCHED
IN THE FACE, A TENT KNOCKED
DOWN.
I WANT TO GET YOUR TAKE ON ALL
OF THIS BECAUSE THE SILENCE FROM
PRESIDENT CIVILITY IS DEAFENING
HERE BECAUSE THEY ARE HIS ALLIES
AFTER ALL.
HE HAS SOME SWAY WITH STHEM.
>> IN A NUMBER OF CASES,
PARTICULARLY WITH THE THREATS OF
VIOLENCE IN MICHIGAN, I WOULD
HOPE THAT THE GOVERNOR OF
MICHIGAN WOULD CALL ON THE
PRESIDENT TO ASK HIS ALLIES TO
BEHAVE IN A CIVIL AND DECENT
MATTER.
THERE IS NO JUSTIFICATION FOR
PEOPLE THREATENING VIOLENCE.
I THINK ONE OF THE STATE
SENATORS IN MICHIGAN SAID THAT
THERE WILL BE BLOOD.
WHAT KIND OF COMMENT IS THAT
FROM AN ELECTED OFFICIAL?
WHY IS IT BEING TOLERATED?
I THINK THE NETWORKS AND THE NEW
YORK TIMES AND OTHERS HAVE A
REAL OBLIGATION TO COVER UNION
VIOLENCE WHEN IT OCCURS AND NOT
HIDE IT.
SO I THINK YOU ARE RAISING A
GOOD POINT AND IT'S ONE THAT WE
SHOULD BE ADDRESSING AND
DEMANDING THAT THE PRESIDENT
CALL ON HIS ALLIES TO EXERCISE
DISCIPLINE AND CIVILITY.
>> SEAN: ALL RIGHT.
DO YOU REMEMBER DURING THE TEA
PARTY RALLIES, YOU WERE SPEAKING
ABOUT THE MEDIA.
THE MEDIA WOULD SEARCH HIGH AND
LOW AND THEY WOULD BE LOOKING
FOR...
SOMETHING NEGATIVE THAT THE TEA
PARTY MOVEMENT WAS SAYING,
USUALLY, THEY WERE KIDS ON THEIR
DAD'S SHOULDERS AND PATRIOTIC
SPEECHES, SINGING THE PLEDGE OF
ALLEGIANCE AND LEAVE THE PLACE
CLEANER THAN WHEN THEY FOUND IT.
I ASK YOU THROUGH THIS PRISM, AS
WE COMPARE THIS TO THE TEA
PARTY, NOW, THERE WAS A VENDOR
IN THE TENT, A HOTDOG GUY, BEEN
WORKING THERE FOR 16 YEARS.
I INTERVIEWED THIS MAN ON MY
RADIO PROGRAM.
THEY RUINEDDED HIS EQUIPMENT AND
KNOCKED OVER HIS FOOD.
>> THEY TRAMPLED THE TENT AND
EVERYTHING I HAD.
THEY WERE UNDER THE TENT,
TABLES, HOTDOG, HOTDOG BUNS,
HOTDOGS, CHILI, ALL OF MY
UTENSILS AND THEN THEY WERE
SAYING, OKAY, MAKE A CHILI DOG
NOW.
EVERYTHING'S ON THE GROUND.
THEY CALLED ME THE "N" WORD --
>> WAIT.
THEY CALLED ME -- YOU ON THE
WRONG SIDE.
I EXPLAINED TO THEM, SEAN, THAT
I WAS THERE TO DO A JOB,
PROSPERITY HIRED ME TO DO A JOB.
THAT'S WHY I WAS THERE.
I AM NOT HERE AND I AM NOT ON
THAT SIDE.
I AM JUST HERE.
SO IT REALLY DIDN'T MAKE A
DIFFERENCE TO THOSE GUYS?
>> YOU WERE HIRED TO DO A JOB,
SO THEY PURPOSELY STARTED
DESTROYING YOUR EQUIPMENT,
CALLING YOU THE "N" WORD AND
UNGLE TOM?
>> THEY DIDN'T CARE.
THEY DIDN'T CARE.
>> SEAN: THE MEDIA DIDN'T COVER
THE VIOLENCE.
IF THIS WAS A TEA PARTY RALLY,
WHAT WOULD THE REACTION BE IN
THE MEDIA?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT IT WOULD
BE.
THIS IS PART OF THE TOTAL BIAS
OF THE MODERN MEDIA IN
PROTECTING THE LEFT EVERY WAY IT
CAN.
I WOULD HOPE THAT A COUPLE OF
CONSERVATIVE LAWYERS LISTENING
TO THAT ON YOUR RADIO SHOW WOULD
OFFER TO REPRESENT HIM PRO BONO
AND FILE A SUIT FOR DAMAGES
AGAINST THE PEOPLE, BECAUSE I
SUSPECT THERE ARE PICTURES OF
WHO THEY ARE.
I SUSPECT THEY'RE VULNERABLE TO
BEING SUED.
I THINK WE NEED TO LEARN TO USE
THE LEFT'S OWN TECHNIQUES
AGAINST THEM.
BUT WE HAVE TO BE MUCH MORE
AGGRESSIVE, IN RAISING THE ISSUE
OF VIOLENCE ON THE LEFT AND IN
DEMANDING THAT IT WOULD BE
POLICED, THE PEOPLE WOULD BE
ARRESTED WHEN NECESSARY AND THAT
THE PRESIDENT HAS A ROLE TO PLAY
HERE AND CALLING ON HIS OWN
ALLIES TO EXERCISE RESTRAINT AND
TO BE DISCIPLINED AND RECOGNIZE
THE RULE OF LAW.
>> SEAN: HOW DO YOU INTERPRET UP
ON, THIS LABOR VIOLENCE, THE
G-20 SUMMIT.
HOW DO YOU INTERPRET THAT,
COMING FROM THE LEFT?
AND THE LANGUAGE OF THE LEFT,
WHICH NEITHER -- NEITHER YOU OR
I WOULD EVER GET AWAY WITH.
>> I THINK THAT WHAT YOU HAVE IS
A MOVEMENT ON OFFENSE WHICH IS
DESPERATELY TRYING TO CHANGE
AMERICA AND TRIES TO BROWBEAT
AND RIDICULE AND INTIMIDATE THE
REST OF US INTO PUTTING UP WITH
ANTI-DEMOCRATIC OPPRESSION BY
VERY MILITANT, SMALL GROUPS.
I THINK WE HAVE TO PROVE THAT WE
ARE PREPARED WHEN NECESSARIES TO
USE THE POLICE, WE ARE PREPARED
WHEN NECESSARY TO FILE LAWSUITS.
AND WE ARE NOT -- WE ARE GOING
TO GO AFTER THEM.
>> SEAN: THESE ARE TWO BIG
LOSSES FOR THE PRESIDENT.
I MEAN, PRESIDENT, BIG SUPPORTER
OF BIG LABOR, WENT THERE THE DAY
BEFORE.
AND THE LEGISLATURE, YOU KNOW,
PASSED RIGHT TO WORK, WHICH BY
THE WAY, ENDS LEGALIZED
STEALING -- NOT RANK-AND-FILE
MEMBERS, I AM TALKING ABOUT THE
UNION LEADERSHIP.
THEY SHOULDN'T BE SPENDING
RANK-AND-FILE MONOPOLITICAL CAM
PAIBS.
SUSAN RICE, THE PRESIDENT TRIED
TO STAND UP FOR HER AND THAT
DIDN'T WORK EITHER.
THIS SHWE INTERPRET THAT AS IT
RELATES TO NEGOTIATIONS WITH THE
PRESIDENT?
>> WELL, LOOK, I THINK THE
NEGOTIATIONS ARE SOMETHING TO
TALK ABOUT.
BUT WHAT WE ARE SEEING IS THE
NATURAL BALANCE OF THINGS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WON A VICTORY.
IT WAS A BIG VICTORY, AN
IMPRESSIVE VICTORY.
I DIDN'T THINK HE COULD DO IT.
HAVING WON THAT VICTORY, THOUGH,
NOW WOE ARE BACK TO REALITY.
THE LONG-TERM TREND IN AMERICA
IS TOWARDS GREATER PRODUCTIVITY,
LESS UNIONISM, PUBLIC REACTION
AGAINST COMPULSORY UNIONISM AND
THE AMBASSADOR RICE MISLED THE
ENTIRE PUBLIC, AND
SHE COULDN'T WITHSTAND THE
STRIEWTNY OF HAVING LIE TO THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE.
>> SEAN: WE HAVE SOME OF BARACK
OBAMA'S BEST FRIENDS, THOSE WHO
LECTURE US ON THE NEED TO PAY
MORE TAXES.
THEY ARE FINDING TAX SHELTERS IN
BERMUDA AND SOME OF THEM ARE
USING EVERY LOOPHOLE IMAGINABLE.
ONE OF THEM IS WARREN BUFFETT.
WE WILL GET YOUR TAKE ON THAT.
AND LATER, WOULD YOU GET YOUR
JOB BACK IF YOU WERE CAUGHT --
THERE YOU GO -- MOKING WEED AT
WORK AND DRINKING?
THESE MEN DID.
THEIR UNIONS HELPED THEM.
WE WILL SHOW YOU THAT, COMING UP
NEXT.
I'M NORA.
AND I'M NATE.
AND THIS IS OUR EMERGEN-C.
[ Nora ]
WHEN YOU RUN YOUR OWN PLACE,
YOU CAN'T MISS A DAY.
SO WE RELY ON EMERGEN-C.
WITH VITAMIN C
FOR IMMUNE SUPPORT
PLUS ENERGIZING B VITAMINS,
OUR REGULARS KNOW
WE'RE SURE TO BE THERE.
GET YOUR FREE SAMPLE
AT EMERGENC.COM.
STAY HEALTHY,
AND FEEL THE GOOD.
TILL YOU FINISH YOUR VEGETABLES.
[ clock ticking ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THERE'S A BETTER WAY...
V8 V-FUSION.
VEGETABLE NUTRITION THEY NEED,
FRUIT TASTE THEY LOVE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
OR...TRY KIDS BOXES!
YOU'LL ALSO CARE ABOUT
OUR NEW OFFER.
YOU GET ACCESS TO NURSES WHO
CAN HELP WITH YOUR QUESONS.
AND YOUR LOVED ONE CAN GE
EXELON PATCH FREE FOR 30 DAYS.
IF THE DOCTOR FEELS
IT'S RIGHT FOR THEM.
IT CANNOCHANGE
HOW THE DIASE PROGRESSES.
HOSPITALIZATION
AND RARELY ATH
HAVE BEEN REPORTED IN PATIENTS
WHO WORE MORE THAN ONE PATCH
AT A TIME.
THE MOST COMMON SIDE EFFECTS
OF EXELON PATCH
ARE NAUSEA, VOMITING,
AND DIARRHEA.
THE LIKELIHOOD AND SEVERITY
OF THESE SIDE EFFECTS
MAY INCREASE
AS THE DOSE INCREASES.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
LOSS OF APPETITE OR WEIGHT.
PATIENTS WHO WEIGH
LESS THAN 110 POUNDS
MAY EXPERIENCE
MORE SIDE EFFECTS.
PEOPLE AT RISK
FOR STOMACH ULCERS
WHO TAKE CERTAIN
OTHER MEDICINES
SHOULD TALK TO THEIR DOCTOR
BECAUSE SERIOUS
STOMACH PROBLEMS
SUCH AS BLEEDING MAY WORSEN.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
SLOW HEART RATE.
THIRTY DAYS OF EXELON PATCH
FREE FOR YOUR LOVED ONE.
ACCESS TO TRAINED NURSES
FOR YOU.
CALL 1-855-999-1399
OR VISIT EXELONPATCHOFFER2.COM.
TIME FOR CITI PRICE REWIND.
BECAUSE YOUR DAUGHTER REALLY
WANTS THAT PINK CASTLE THING.
AND YOU REALLDON'T WANT
TO PAY MORE THAN YOU HAVE TO.
ONLY CITI PRICE REWIND
AUTOMATICALLY SEARCHES
FOR THE LOWEST PRICE.
AND IF IT FINDONE, YOU GET
REFUNDED THE DIFFERENCE.
JUST USE YOUR CITI CARD
AND REGISTER YOUR PURCHASE
ONLINE.
HAVE A SUPER SPARKLY DAY!
OK.
[ Male Announcer ] NOW ALL
YOUEED IS A MAGIC CARRIAGE.
CITI PRICE REWIND.
START SAVING
AT CITI.COM/PRICEREWIND.
>> SEAN: YOU MAY BE SHOCKED TO
LEARN THAT ONE OF BARACK OBAMA'S
RICHEST AND MOST HIGH-PROFILE
SUPPORTERS IS NOT PAYING HIS
FAIR SHARE IN TAXES.
ONCE AGAIN, WE ARE SEEING
LIBERAL HYPOCRISY IN DISPLAY.
THE NET WORTH OF THE GOOGLE
DIRECTOR IS WORTH $18 BILLION.
DESPITE BEING AN OBAMA DONOR AND
SERVING ON THE COUNCIL OF
ADVISERS ON SCIENCE AND
DECKNOLOGY, MR. SCHMITT FALLS
INTO THE CATEGORY OF DO AS I
SAY, KNOW AS I DO.
HERE'S WHY.
IN RECENT DAYS, HIS COMPANY,
GOOGLE, HAS MADE HEADLINES, FOR
NOT EXACTLY PAYING THEIR FAIR
SHARE.
SCHMITT, AT THE HELM OF THE
COMPANY WHEN ACCORDING TO A
REPORT BY BLOOMBERG NEWS, GOOGLE
AVOIDED $2 BILLION IN WORLDWIDE
INCOME TAXES IN 2011, SHIFTING
$9.8 MILLION IN REVENUES INTO A
BERMUDA SHELL COMPANY, ALMOST
DOUBLE THE TOTAL FROM YEARS
BEFORE.
WHILE THE REPORT NOTES THAT THE
MONEY WAS MOVED LEGALLY, THIS
SEAM SEEMS LIKE A DIRECT
CONTRADICTION TO PRESIDENT
OBAMA'S NON-STOP LECTURES ABOUT
CORPORATE GREED AND PAYING YOUR
FAIR SHARE.
MR. SCHMITT HAS SAID, HE'S PROUD
OF HIS TAX MOVES.
MORE INTERESTING, HE WAS RUMORED
TO BE AT THE TOP OF THE
PRESIDENT'S CABINET RECRUITING
CLASS FOR A SECOND TERM.
THOUGH HE PREEMPTIVELY DECLINED
AN OFFER, POSSIBLE POSITIONS
WERE SECRETARY OF THE TREASURY,
EVEN THE SECRETARY OF
BUSINESSES.
HERE WE HAVE THE PRESIDENT'S
BILLIONAIRE BUDDY AT GOOGLE,
HELPING TO SHELTER HIS COMPANY'S
MONEY IN A SHELL COMPANY IN
BERMUDA TO AVOID PAYING HIS FAIR
SHARE AND HE IS BEING CONSIDERED
FOR A CABINET POST.
JOINING ME IS FORMER SPEAKER OF
THE HOUSE NEWT GINGRICH AND
PRESIDENTIAL CANDIDATE NEWT
GINGRICH.
AND WARREN BUFFETT, FORBES
MAGAZINE HAS A PIECE ABOUT
HIM -- MASSIVE AMOUNTS OF TAX
DOLLARS HE IS NOT PAYING BECAUSE
HE IS USING EVERY LOOPHOLE
IMAGINABLE, NOT TO PAY.
A LITTLE IRONIC.
>> I THINK THE HOUSE REPUBLICANS
OUGHT TO PASS THE GOOGLE/BUFFETT
TAX BILL, PROVIDING THAT EVERY
AMERICAN SHOULD HAVE ACCESS TO
AT LEAST AS MANY DEDUCTIONS AND
LOOPHOLES AS WARREN BUFFETT AND
ERIC SCHMITT.
WE SHOULD TAKE ADVANTAGE OF
LIBERALS BEING HUMAN AND TRYING
TO PROTECT THEMSELVES AND SIMPLY
SUGGEST THAT EVERYBODY ELSE
OUGHT TO BE THE SAME RIGHT.
AND I THINK THAT SHOULD BE PART
OF OF OUR ANSWER TO PRESIDENT
OBAMA'S CONSTANT DEMAND FOR
HIGHER TAXES.
THESE ARE HIS ALLIES, DOING WHAT
THEY -- IT IS LEGAL.
AND SO WE SHOULD TRY TO EXTEND
THAT LEGALITY TO THE MIDDLE
CLASS.
I THINK -- IT WOULD BE VERY
EDUCATIONAL TO SUDDENLY CALL A
HEARING AND ASK PEOPLE LIKE
WARREN BUFFETT TO COME IN AND
EDUCATE THE WHOLE COUNTRY ON HOW
THE MIDDLE CLASS COULD USE EVERY
LOOPHOLE TO AVOID PAYING TAXES.
>> SEAN: THIS WAS ON NATIONAL
REVIEW ONLINE, 36 OF PRESIDENT
OBAMA'S EXECUTIVE OFFICE STAFF
OWE $$830,000 IN BACK TAXES.
WHY DO I THINK IF IT WAS YOU OR
ME -- MADE A MODEL CITIZEN
BEFORE THE NATION -- I THINK
THERE WOULD BE A DOUBLE STANDARD
IN HANDLING SOME OF THAT.
>> WELL, THIS IS AN ESSENTIAL
PART OF THE CONSERVATIVE
ARGUMENT ABOUT BIG GOVERNMENT.
BIG GOVERNMENT'S INHERENTLY
UNFAIR T. INHERENTLY HAS
ADVANTAGES FOR FRIENDS AND
INHERENTLY TAKES CARE OF
INSIDERS, CREATING A SYSTEM,
WHICH IS THE OPPOSITE OF THE
RULE OF LAW AND THE OPPOSITE OF
A FREE SOCIETY.
THAT'S WHY CONSERVATIVES HAVE
ARGUED FOR SMALLER GOVERNMENT
BECAUSE THESE THINGS ARE ALMOST
INEVITABLE BECAUSE PEOPLE WHO
HAVE POWER TAKE CARE OF
THEMSELVES AND THEY TAKE CARE OF
THEIR FRIENDS?
>> SEAN: I HAVE BEEN WAITING FOR
THE HOUSE LEADERSHIP, THERE HAS
BEEN A LOT OF FIGHTING, TEA
PARTY CONSERVATIVES SAY THEY
HAVE BEEN PURGED FROM THEIR
COMMITTEES AND THE NEGOTIATE --
THE NEGOTIATIONS WITH THE
PRESIDENT -- YOUR ADVICE WAS,
PASS A SERIES OF BILLS.
THEY HAVEN'T DONE THAT YET.
DO YOU THINK THEY HAVE TIME TO
DO THAT?
>> SURE, THEY HAVE TIME TO DO
IT.
BUT THEY HAVE BEEN CAUGHT UP IN,
I BEING, A LOSING PROPOSITION.
THEY ARE NOT GOING TO GET A REAL
AGREEMENT OUT OF BARACK OBAMA
BEFORE THE END OF THE YEAR.
HE JUST WON AN ELECTION.
HE IS FEELING LIKE HE IS
DOMINANT WHARKTS JAPANESE USED
TO CALL VICTORY DISEASE.
HE IS MAKING OUTLANDISH
SUGGESTIONS, SUCH AS ELIMINATING
THE DEBT CEILING PERMANENTLY, SO
THE PRESIDENT COULD RUN UP ANY
LEVEL OF DEFICIT THAT HE WANTS
TO.
THIS IS A GOOD TIME FOR THE
HOUSE TO PASS, I WOULD PASS TWO
BILLS, A COMPLETE EXTENSION OF
EVERY SINGLE TAX CUT AND PASS AN
EXTENSION OF EVERY PASS CUT
EXCEPT THE TOP.
PASS BOTH OF THEM.
SEND THEM TO THE SENATE AND SAY,
WE ARE NOT DEALING WITH ANYTHING
ELSE.
WE ARE NOT PLAYING GAMES.
WE WANT TO MAKE SURE THE MIDDLE
CLASS DOESN'T FACE A TAX
INCREASE.
YOU PICK.
YOU PASS SOMETHING.
GET IT DONE.
BUT NOW IT'S UP TO THE DEMOCRATS
IN THE SENATE AND THE PRESIDENT.
YOU ARE NOW RESPONSIBLE FOR THE
MIDDLE-CLASS TAX INCREASE.
>> SEAN: I HAVE A NAME FOR THE
BILL.
I WANT TO SEE IF YOU CAN COME UP
WITH A BETTER ONE.
I HATE WHEN YOU TOP ME, BUT IF
IT'S BETTER, I GO ALONG WITH A
GOOD IDEA.
HOW ABOUT THE STOP STEALING FROM
OUR KIDS AND GRANDKIDS BILL OF
2012?
>> THAT'S THE SPENDING BILL.
THAT COMES NEXT.
>> SEAN: NO, NO, I WANT THAT --
SPENDING --
[OVERLAPPING DIALOGUE]
>> THAT'S MY POINT.
THERE ARE TWO STEPS HERE.
I THINK IT IS HELPFUL FOR THE
REPUBLICAN PARTY TO MAKE VERY
CLEAR IT DOES NOT WANT TAXES TO
GO UP ON WORKING AMERICANS.
AND I THINK THEY HAVE BEEN OUT
MANUFACTURED BY OBAMA.
THEY NEED TO GET PAST THAT AND
MAKE CLEAR, WE DON'T WANT TAXES
FOR THE MIDDLE CLASS TO GO UP.
SECOND, THEY NEED TO MAKE SURE
THAT WE HAVE A BIG FIGHT OVER
OUR CHILDREN AND GRANDCHILDREN
AND THAT STARTS JANUARY 3.
>> SEAN: WE WILL BE BACK AFTER
OUR CHRISTMAS VACATION AND WE
WILL BE BACK FIGHTING ON THE
SAME THING.
MR. SPEAKER, GOOD TO SEE YOU,
THANK YOU.
COMING UP, THEY WERE CUTE CAM
REMARKS DRINKING, SMOKING POT ON
THEIR LUNCH BREAK.
GUESS WHAT?
THEY WERE QUICKLY FIRED.
BUT NOW THEY HAVE THEIR JOBS
BACK.
WHAT HAPPENED?
WHERE DID THEY WORK?
WHY DID THEY GET REHIRED?
AND HARRY BELAFONTE HAS LAST AND
SOUND ADVICE FOR THE PRESIDENT.
YOU ARE NOT GOING TO BELIEVE
WHAT HE THINKS OBAMA SHOULD DO
WITH THE DISSENTERS AND MEET THE
FAMILY OF A BRAVE MARINE,
IRAQ/AFGHANISTAN WAR HERO, IN
JAIL IN MEXICO AND HAS BEEN
SINCE AUGUST.
AND THE OBAMA ADMINISTRATION
HASN'T HELPED HIM YET.
WHY?
I HAVE A COLD,
AND I TOOK NYQUIL,
BUT I'M STILL STUBBED UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus Liquid Gels
SPEEDS RELIEF
TO YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A DECONGESTANT
FOR YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
THANKS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
THLET'FOR AN IDEA.S -
A GRAND IDEA CALLED AMERICA.
THE IDEA THAT
IF YOU WORK HARD,
IF YOU HAVE A DREAM,
IF YOU WORK WITH
YOUR NEIGHBORS...
YOU CAN DO MOST ANYTHING.
THIS LED TO OTHER IDEAS
LIKE LERTY
AND ROCK 'N' ROLL.
TO FREE MARKETS,
FREE ENTERPRISE,
AND FREE REFILLS.
IT PUT A MAN ON THE MOON
AND A PHONE IN YOUR POCKET.
OUR COUNTRY'S GONE THROUGH A LOT
OVER THE CENTURIES AND A HALF.
BUT THIS IDEA ISN'T FRAGILE.
WHEN TIMES GET TOUGH,
IT RALLIES US AS ONE.
EVERY DAY, MORE PEOPLE
BELIEVE IN THE AMERICAN IDEA
AND WHEN THEY DO,
THE DREAM COMES TRUE.
WE'RE GRATEFUL
TO BE A PART OF IT.
BY SHOWING YOU
THE APARTMENT BUILDING
WHERE THE FIRE WAS.
WHEN THINGS LIKE THIS HAPPEN,
I THINK YOU FIND
A NEW PERSPECTIVE ON LIFE.
RED CROSS PUT US IN A HOTEL
SO WE WERE ABLE
TO STAY TOGETHER.
WE'RE STRONG
AND IF WE OVERCAME THAT
OR IF WE CAN OVERCOME THAT...
WE CAN OVERCOME ANYTHING.
[ SNIFFLES ]
♪
>> SEAN: WELCOME BACK TO
"HANNITY."
ONE MAY THINK THAT DRINKING
ALCOHOL AND SMOKE MARIJUANA ON
THE JOB WOULD BE REASON ENOUGH
TO GET FIRED.
IT IS NOT THE CASE WHEN IT COMES
TO -- SURPRISE, SURPRISE --
UNION MEMBERS.
YOU MAY REMEMBER THE DETROIT
AUTO WORKERS, FIRED WHEN THEY
WERE CAUGHT RED HANDED WITH
EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITY.
AFTER DIGGING THROUGH THEIR
BIG-LABOR CONTRACTS, THEY GOT
THEIR DISMISSALS REVERSED.
SO SYMBOLIC OF WHAT IS HAPPENING
IN DETROIT, LACK OF
ACCOUNTABILITY AND OVERWHELMING
SENSE OF ENTITLEMENT, WHICH IS
DECLINING THE CITY, WHICH IS
HEADED FOR BANKRUPTCY.
OF 563,000 PEOPLE OVER 16 WHO
ARE ELIGIBLE TO WORK, 250,000 OF
THEM, OR 46%, DO NOT HAVE A JOB
IN DETROIT.
IN FACT, THEY ARE NOT LOOKING.
IF THAT IS NOT ENOUGH, OUT OF
264,000 HOUSEHOLDS IN THE CITY,
ALMOST 100,000 OF THEM, 35% NOW
HAVE TO RELY ON FOOD STAMPS.
JOINING ME WITH THE REACTION TO
THE DECLINE AND PERHAPS THE
PREVIEW OF WHAT MAY BECOME OF
MANY OTHER U.S. CITIES FROM THE
DAILY CALLER AND WILL A FOX NEWS
CONTRIBUTOR.
WELCOME TO YOU BOTH.
I WANT TO BE CLEAR.
I SPENT OVER A DECADE WORKING IN
THE RESTAURANT BUSINESS AND IN
CONSTRUCTION BUSINESS.
EVERY JOB IMAGINABLE.
THIS IS NOT ABOUT WORKERS TO ME.
I RESPECT THE HARD WORK -- I
DON'T CARE IF PEOPLE JOIN A
UNION.
THEY SHOULDN'T BE FORCED TO,
WHICH IS MY CASE.
WITH THAT SAID, WHEN YOU LOOK AT
A CITY LIKE DETROIT AND THE
DECISION LIKE THIS -- THEY'RE
SMOKING POT.
THEY ARE DRINKING, HOW DID THEY
GET THEIR JOB BACK?
IF I DID THAT EYE AM OUTTA HERE.
>> WELL, OBVIOUSLY, IT'S
TROUBLING IF WORKERS -- WHAT
THEY DO ON THEIR RECREATION TIME
AFFECTS THEIR WORKPLACE.
>> SEAN: LOOK AT THIS.
THEY ARE DRINKING HEAVILY.
THEY ARE SMOKING WEED, GOING
BACK TO BUILD OUR CARS.
THAT'S NOT PROBLEMATIC FOR YOU?
>> CONCEPTUALLY IT'S
PROBLEMATIC, WITHOUT KNOWING
ANYTHING PLEASURE I HAVE SEEN.
BUT ON THE LOGIC PICTURE, WHICH
YOU STARTED OUT WITH, THE
AMERICAN WORKERS, THE ENVY OF
THE WORLD.
AUTOMOTIVE INDUSTRY IS THE ENVY
OF THE WORLD.
SO I THINK THAT THE PROBLEMS IN
THE WORKPLACE ARE PROBLEMS THAT
DETROIT IS IN A SITUATION THAT
OTHER CITIES HAVE FOUND
THEMSELVES IN.
NEW YORK CITY WAS ON LIFE
SUPPORT AT ONE POINT.
BUT IT CAME BACK.
I THINK THAT THE AMERICAN
WORKERS, THEY WILL WORK THROUGH
THIS PERIOD WITH THEIR
GOVERNMENT.
>> SEAN: THEY LOST HALF THE
POPULATION OF DETROIT.
YOU HEARD THE STATISTICS.
THEY ARE BULLDOZING ENTIRE
NEIGHBORHOODS BECAUSE HALF THE
POPULATION'S GONE, TO
CONSOLIDATE SERVICES.
THEY LOST ALL OF THOSE CAR
MANUFACTURING JOBS, THE UNIONS
PARTLY RESPONSIBLE?
LEADERSHIP?
>> THE AUTO INDUSTRY IS NOT THE
ENVY OF THE WORLD.
I LOVE THIS COUNTRY -- I WISH IT
WERE.
WE HAVE -- LOOK, A LOT OF GREAT
PEOPLE IN UNION, I WORKED IN A
UNION FACTORY IN COLLEGE.
I CAN TELL YOU, BECAUSE YOU ARE
UNION, IT DOESN'T MEAN YOU ARE A
BAD EMPLOYEE.
BUT MANY MIDE YOKER EMPLOYEES
ARE PROTECTED BY THE UNIONS AND
THIS HURTS UNIONS.
THERE IS A REASON, DETROIT, ONE
OF THE BIRTH PLACES OF THE LABOR
UNION BECAME A RIGHT-TO-WORK
STATE -- BECAUSE OF NONSENSE
LIKE THIS.
IT IS SELF-DISCREDITING, TO
PROTECT PEOPLE WHO ARE WORKING
WITH HEAVY MACHINERY, GETTING
HIGH ON THEIR BRAKE BREAKS.
>> EVEN IF YOU ACCEPT THAT
REASONING -- WHICH I DON'T -
EVEN IF YOU ACCEPT THAT
REASONING, IT ISN'T THAT THE
SITUATION IN DETROIT IS GOING TO
LEAD TO THE DECLINE OF AMERICAN
CITIES?
>> WHY CAN'T YOU LOOK AT
SOMETHING AS BASIC AS THAT SAY
YOU HAVE TO FIRE THOSE GUYS.
THEY DON'T REFLECT EVERY WORKER.
AS A MATTER OF FACT, GOOD
WORKERS, THEIR NAME AND
REPUTATION IS HURT BECAUSE OF
SCENES LIKE THIS AND PEOPLE
SEEING THIS.
>> I AM SAYING OWNERSHIP, THE
MANAGEMENT AND THE OWNERSHIP
ENTERED INTO INTO AN AGREEMENT
WITH THE WORKERS AND SET UP A
PROCESS, IT DIDN'T WORK OUT--
>>> BUT WHY ARE THERE ALL OF
THESE -- TO TUCKER, LOOK AT
MISSISSIPPI AND TENNESSEE AND
ALABAMA.
ALL OF THESE STATES, GUESS WHAT?
NOW THEY ARE BUILDING CARS --
>> OF COURSE, THEY ARE.
>> SEAN: AND IN INDIA AND OTHER
COUNTRIES.
>> UNIONS DON'T HELP -- SOME
UNIONS DO -- A LOT OF UNIONS
HAVE SOLD OUT THEIR OWN WORKERS.
YOU SEE DEPRESSED WAGES BECAUSE
OF LOW-SKILL IMMIGRATION,
SUPPORTED BY THE UNIONS, FOR
REASONS THAT ARE NOT CLEAR AT
ALL.
AT THE BEHEST OF THE DEMOCRATIC
PARTY, FOR WHICH THEY ARE THE
MOST FAITHFUL GET-OUT-THE VOTES.
TRULY--
>>> NOW, WE HAVE THIS VIOLENCE
TAKE PLACE, YOU SAW THE VIDEO
AND IF IT WAS A TEA PARTY
MEMBER, I TALKED TO THE HOTDOG
GUY, WHO WILL BE ON GRETA LATER
TONIGHT -- AND I JUST PLAYED HIM
WITH NEWT GINGRICH, USING THE
"N" WORD -- THE "N" WORD WAS USE
THE AGAINST HIM.
HE WAS CALLED AN UNCLE TOM.
HIS EQUIPMENT WAS RUINED.
HIS FOOD WAS KNOCKED OVER.
IF THIS HAPPENED IN A TEA PARTY
RALLY, NOT A LABOR RALLY, IT
WOULD BE FRONT-PAGE NEWS AND THE
LEFT WOULD BE HAVING A FIT.
HOW DOES THIS HAPPEN, UP ON
VIOLENCE?
G-20 SUMMIT, VIOLENCE.
LABOR MOVEMENT, VIOLENCE THIS
WEEK.
NO PROMINENT LIBERAL SPEAKS OUT.
>> I AM A PRODUCT OF THE SOCIAL
JUSTICE MOVEMENT FOR CIVIL
RIGHTS, A NONVIOLENT MOVEMENT
YOU?
>> ARE RIGHT.
>> THOSE WHO CAME OUT FOR
NONVIOLENCE, VIOLENCE WAS
VISITED UPON THEM.
THEY HAVE TO BE PREPARED TO PAY
THE CONSEQUENCES FOR BEING
NONVIOLENT.
WHEN PEOPLE BREAK THE LAW, THEY
HAVE TO GO TO JAIL.
WHETHER THE MEDIA--
>>> BUT IF A TEA PARTY MEMBER
USED THE "N" WORD AGAIN A GUY--
THE BIG LABOR -- NO REPORTS ON
ANY MAJOR NETWORKS.
>> I AM NOT FOR IT UNDER ANY
CIRCUMSTANCES.
I NEVER CONDONE THE "N" WORD--
>>> RUINED HIS EQUIPMENT.
>> BUT THE OTHER THICK THAT WAS
MENTIONED THAT HAS TO BE
RESPONDED TO, THE ROLE OF UNIONS
IN CIVIL RIGHT, CHILD LABOR LAW,
WORKPLACE SAFETY AND OVER--
>>> LAST QUESTION -- IS IT WRONG
TO SAY TO PEOPLE, YOU CAN'T WORK
UNLESS YOU JOIN THE UNION, PAY
DUES AND THAT MONEY IS USED FOR
POLITICAL --
>> IF IT GOES THROUGH THE
DEMOCRATIC PROCESS AND IS PASSED
BY ELECTED OFFICIALS AND THE
WORKERS, YES.
>> SEAN: YOU ARE NOT PRO-CHOICE?
>> I AM FOR ORGANIZED LABOR.
>> SEAN: WOW.
SO THAT FORCE PEOPLE -- TAKE
THEIR MONEY --
>> PROTECT THE RIGHTS OF WORKERS
IN AMERICA.
>> SEAN: LICENSED STEALING.
>> PROTECT THE RIGHTS OF WORKERS
IN AMERICA WHO, HAVE BEEN IN
EVERY INSTANCE, WHEN THERE ISN'T
REGULATION, THEY GET ABUSED.
>> SEAN: THANKS.
APPRECIATE IT.
STILL AHEAD, MEDIA MASH.
WE COUNT THE MANY WAYS THAT THE
MEDIA BIAS IS ON DISPLAY.
ALSO, HARRY BELLE FOBTY -- HARRY
BELAFONTE IS LAUNCHING IDIOTIC
COMMENTS, OFFERING PRESIDENT
OBAMA ADVICE.
AND YOU WON'T BELIEVE WHAT THE
ESPN ANALYSTS ARE SAYING ABOUT
THE REDSKINNINGS QUARTERBACK,
RG3, ROBERT GRIFFIN III.
WE HAVE THE TAPE, COMING UP.
STRAIGHT AHEAD.
COPD INCLUDES CHRONIC
BRONCHITIS AND EMPHYSEMA.
SPIRIVA HELPS CONTROL
MY COPD SYMPTOMS
BY KEEPING MY AIRWAYS
OPEN FOR 24 HOURS.
PLUS, IT REDUCES COPD FLARE-UPS.
SPIRIVA IS THE ONLY ONCE-DAILY
INHALED COPD MAINTENANCE
TREATMENT THAT DOES BOTH.
SPIRIVA HANDIHALER TIOTROPIUM
BROMIDE INHALATION POWDER
DOES NOT REPLACE FAST-ACTING
INHALERS FOR SUDDEN SYMPTOMS.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU HAVE
KIDNEY PROBLEMS, GLAUCOMA,
TROUBLE URINATING, OR
AN ENLARGED PROSTATE.
THESE MAY WORSEN WITH SPIRIVA.
DISCUSS ALL MEDICINES
YOU TAKE, EVEN EYE DROPS.
STOP TAKING SPIRIVA AND SEEK
IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
IF YOUR BREATHING
SUDDENLY WORSENS,
YOUR THROAT OR TONGUE
SWELLS, YOU GET HIVES,
VISION CHANGES OR EYE PAIN,
OR PROBLEMS PASSING URINE.
OTHER SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE
DRY MOUTH AND CONSTIPATION.
NOTHING CAN REVERSE COPD
SPIRIVA HELPS ME BREATHE BETTER.
(BLOWING SOU)
ASK YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT SPIRIVA.
they see more than themselves.
look in the mirror,
So we celebrate our year-end
with the "share the love" event.
Get a great deal on a new Subaru
and 250 dollars goes to your
choice of five charities.
By the end of this, our fifth
year,
our total can reach almost 25
million dollars.
It's a nice reflection on us
all.
Now through January 2nd.
Get 0% APR financing for 36
months on a 2013 Subaru Forester
and we'll donate 250 dollars to
your choice of 5 charities.
>>
>> SEAN: WELCOME BACK TO
"HANNITY."
EVEN THOUGH 50 MILLION AMERICANS
VOTED AGAINST PRESIDENT OBAMA,
HIS SUPPORTERS CANNOT SEEM TO
COMPREHEND WHY HE IS RECEIVING
SUCH OPPOSITION TO HIS RADICAL
AGEND A. HARRY BELAFONTE HAS
DOWNRIGHT DISTURBING ADVICE, HOW
OBAMGA SHOULD DEAL WITH THE
SENATORS.
HE WAS ASKED ABOUT REPUBLICANS
PUSHING REFORM TO THE COUNT RE'S
BROKEN ENTITLEMENT SYSTEM.
BELIEVE IT OR NOT, THIS IS WHAT
HE SAID.
>> PLENTY OF AMERICAN PEOPLE IN
THEIR MATURITY DECLARED FULLY,
WE WANT WHAT BARACK OBAMA IS
TALKING ABOUT.
WE WANT OUR COUNTRY TO GO IN
THAT DIRECTION.
WHAT FASCINATES ME IS IN THE
FACE OF MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
EXPRESSING THEIR DESIRE, THE
WHOLE POLITICAL ESTABLISHMENT
DEFINING ITS GAME THAT THERE
SHOULD BE THIS LINGERING
INFESTATION OF REALLY CORRUPT
PEOPLE WHO SIT TRYING TO
DISMANTLE THE WISHES OF THE
PEOPLE, THE MANDATE THAT HAS
BEEN GIVEN TO BARACK OBAMA AND I
DON'T KNOW WHAT MORE THEY WANT.
THE ONLY THING LEFT FOR BARACK
OBAMA TO DO IS TO WORK AND
DICTATE TO THE WORLD AND THROW
ALL OF THESE GUYS IN JAIL.
THEY ARE VIOLATING THE AMERICAN
DESIRE.
>> SEAN: YEAH, THROW 'EM IN
JAIL.
PRESIDENT OBOTTOM AACT LIKE A
DICTATOR.
JOINING ME WITH THE REACTION,
KIMBERLY GUILFOYLE AND TARA
DOWDELL IS HERE.
THIS IS THE SAME BELAFONTE WHO
SAID OF NELSON MANDELA.
WE SALUTE YOU.
WE WANT TO SEE YOU AND YOUR
FELLOW POLITICAL PRISONERS
FREED.
REACTION?
>> WELL, I THINK THAT HARRY
BELAFONTE WAS SAYING HAD HE SAID
IN JEST--
>>> IN JEST?
>> HE WAS JOKING AROUND.
HE DIDN'T MEAN IT--
>>> I HAVE A WHOLE LIST OF
THINGS HE SAID IN JEST.
>> YOU HAVE THE LIST OF HIM
CRITICIZING PRESIDENT OBAMA,
WHICH HE DID.
>> SEAN: COMPARING THE
ROSENBERGS TO POLITICAL
PRISONERS AND THE BUSH
ADMINISTRATION AND THE DHS TO
THE GASTOPO AND --
>> HE CRITICIZED OBAMA TOO AND
JAY-Z.
>> SEAN: COP KILLER -- I MEAN,
HOW EXTREME CAN YOU GET?
>> WELL, I THINK--
>>> YOU DON'T SEEM FAZED AT ALL.
>> HE WAS SAYING IT IN JEST--
>>> EVERY DUMB THING --
>> EVERYBODY STARTED LAUGHING--
>>> I SAY DUMB THINGS IN JEST,
PEOPLE START CAMPAIGNS TO STOP
ME.
>> THEY DO.
BECAUSE THEY KNOW YOU ARE NOT
KIDDING.
HE IS PREPARING FOR A ROLE.
THIS IS A SCRIPT HAIS
UNBELIEVABLE.
WHEN HE WAS CRITICIZING
PRESIDENT OBAMA IT'S BECAUSE HE
WASN'T CHOVEZ ENOUGH -- IT
WASN'T FAR SOCIALIST OR LIBERAL
ENOUGH.
HE IS QUITE SERIOUS ABOUT WHAT
HE IS SAYING.
THIS IS THE DIRECTION THAT HE
BELIEVES THE COUNTRY SHOULD BE
GOING.
HE SEEMS TO DESCRIBE A PLURALITY
THAT DIDN'T WANT PRESIDENT OBAMA
TO BE RE-ELECTED AND OUTRIGHT
REJECTED HIS LIBERAL AGENDA.
BUT THAT SEEMS TO HAVE FALLEN ON
DEAF EARS OR HARRY BELAFONTE'S
NOT LISTENING.
>> SEAN: DO YOU LIKE RG3 AS MUCH
AS I DO?
I AM A JETS FAN.
SO HE WAS IMPRESSED WITH HIM, AS
A PERSON?
>> RIGHT,.
>> SEAN: AS AN INDIVIDUAL, ISN'T
HE AMAZING?
>> HE IS.
>> SEAN: HE WAS ONCE ASKED ABOUT
WHO HE FEARS, HE SAID GOD.
I FEAR GOD.
>> GOOD ANSWER.
>> SEAN: GOOD PERSON.
GOOD HEART.
GOOD SOUL.
HERE'S WHAT ESPN --
>> THIS IS TERRIBLE.
>> SEAN: THIS ANALYST HAD TO SAY
ABOUT HIM.
ROB PARKER.
LISTEN TO THIS.
>> MY QUESTION, WHICH IS JUST A
STRAIGHT, HONEST QUESTION, IS HE
A CORN BALL BROTHER --
>> WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
>> YEAH, EXPLAIN THAT.
>> HE'S NOT REALLY.
>> HE'S BLACK.
BUT HE IS NOT DOWN WITH THE
CAUSE.
HE IS NOT ONE OF US.
HE IS KINDA BLACK.
BUT HE'S NOT REALLY THE GUY YOU
WANT TO HANG OUT WITH --
>> WHY IS THAT YOUR QUESTION?
>> BECAUSE THAT'S HOW I WANT TO
FIND OUT ABOUT HIM.
I DON'T KNOW BECAUSE I KEEP
HEARING THESE THINGS.
HE HAS A WHITE FIANCEE AND ALL
OF THIS STUFF ABOUT HE IS A
REPUBLICAN -- THERE IS NO
INFORMATION AT ALL -- I AM
TRYING TO DIG DEEPER INTO WHY HE
HAS AN ISSUE.
>> SEAN: HE DOESN'T HAVE THE
ISSUE.
>> THAT'S CRAZY.
IT'S AWFUL.
A HATE-FILLED SPEECH.
THOSE ARE RACIST COMMENTS.
HE HAS A WHITE FIANCEE, HE'S A
REPUBLICAN.
HE WANTS TO DISAVOW AND SAY HE'S
NOT AFRICAN-AMERICAN.
IT'S VERY STRANGE BEHAVIOR AND
REALLY RUDE.
>> SEAN: REACTION?
>> I AM IN SHOCK FOR TWO
REASONS.
NUMBER 1, I THINK HIS COMMENTS
WERE TERRIBLE, TO CRITICIZE A
MAN FOR HAVING A WHITE FIANCEE.
AWFUL.
I AM SHOCKED BECAUSE I AGREE
WITH YOU, SEAN HANNITY.
THIS IS A BREAKING NEWS ALERT!
TARA DOWDELL AGREES WITH SEAN
HANNITY.
ITS COMMENTS WERE WAY OUT OF
LINE -- AND IT HAS NOTHING TO DO
WITH SPORTS?
>> AN HONEST DISAGREEMENT WITH
SUSAN RICE BECAUSE SHE KNEW --
WE KNEW THAT THIS WAS NOT
RELATED TO youtube.
SHE SAID IT FIVE TIMES.
IT'S A WAR ON WOMEN AND IT'S
RACISM.
THIS IS AN ONGOING FALSE
NARRATIVE ABOUT REPUBLICANS.
I AM SICK OF IT BECAUSE I DON'T
KNOW CONSERVATIVES THAT ARE
RACIST.
I DON'T.
THEY MIGHT BE SOME.
THEY ARE NOT FRIENDS OF OURS.
THEY ARE NOT IN THE REPUBLICAN
PARTY AND IF THEY ARE, I WANT
THEM OUT.
I AM GETTING FED UP AND SICK AND
TIRED OF IT.
NBC IS THE WORST.
THEY PLAY THE RACE CARD EVERY
SINGLE DAY THERE.
>> OKAY.
NOW SEE, THIS IS WHERE YOU LOSE
ME.
I WAS WITH YOU, I WAS WITH YOU,
SEAN.
NO.
HERE'S MY THING.
I DON'T THINK THIS IS A
NARRATIVE BEING PUSHED.
WHAT JOHN McCAIN SAID ABOUT
SUSAN RICE AND REMEMBER THE
CONTEXT.
SUSAN RICE HAD NO ROLE AND
RESPONSIBILITY--
>>> SHE KNEW WITHIN --
>> WAIT, WAIT--
>>> WITHIN HOURS.
>> SHE HAD NO ROLE AND
RESPONSIBILITY.
WHY IS JOHN McCANE MORE UPSET
WITH HER--
>>> HE IS MORE UPSET WITH THE
PRESIDENT.
>> HE IS MORE UPSET WITH THE
HE SAID, LET'S HAVE A FULL
HEARING.
>> SEAN: WE HAVE TO GO.
YOU ARE YELLING IN MY EAR.
IT'S TERRIBLE.
THANK YOU.
>> THANKS, SEAN.
>> SEAN: UP NEXT, MEDIA MASH
WITH BRENT BOZEL AND THE WORST
EXAMPLES OF LIBERAL MEDIA BIAS.
WE NEED TO HELP THIS MAN IN THE
PICTURE.
AN EX-MARINE, A HERE FRO IRAQ
AND AFGHANISTAN, BEING HELD IN A
MEXICAN PRISON.
HE HAS BEEN THERE SINCE AUGUST,
BEING DETAINED FOR TRYING TO
REGISTER -- IN OTHER WORDS, HE
WENT IN AND TRIED TO REGISTER IN
MEXICO.
WHERE IS THE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION TO GET THIS GUY
FREE FOR CHRISTMAS?!
STRAIGHT AHEAD.
MY MODERATE TO SEVERE
PLAQUE PSORIASIS.
I DECIDED ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
♪
[ Spa Lady ]
I STARTED ENBREL.
IT'S CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO PROVIDE CLEARER SKIN.
[ RV Guy ] ENBREL MAY NOT WORK
FOR EVERYONE --
AND MAY NOT CLEAR YOU
COMPLETELY,
BUT FOR MANY, IT GETS SKIN
CLEARER FAST, WITHIN 2 MONTHS,
AND KEEPS IT CLEARER
UP TO 9 MONTHS.
[ Male Announcer ]
BECAUSE ENBREL®, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL,
EVENTS INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS, LYMPHOMA,
OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING ENBREL,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START ENBREL IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON ENBREL, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING,
OR PALENESS.
IF YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH, ASK
YOUR DERMATOLOGIST ABOUT ENBREL.
>> SEAN: WELCOME BACK TO
"HANNITY."
WELCOME BACK TO MEDIA MASH.
THIS WEEK, THE LIBERAL MEDIA
NEWS COULDN'T HELP THEIR
LEFT-WING BIAS WITH THE
RIGHT-TO-WORK LEGISLATION.
HERE TO EXPLAIN IT, NONE OTHER
THAN THE PRESIDENT OF THE MEDIA
RESEARCH CENTER, BROTHER BOZEL.
HOW ARE YOU?
>> BROTHER, HANNITY, HOW ARE WE
DOING.
>> SEAN: DOING GOOD.
WE HAVE ALL OF THIS UNFOLD.
STEVEN CROWDER, PUNCHED, NOT
PROVOKING ANYBODY.
WE HAVE ALL OF THIS VIOLENCE --
NONE OF THE NETWORKS COVERED.
IT THERE IS A GUY WHO WAS THERE,
16 YEARS, HAS A HOTDOG STAND IN
LANSING, WHO WAS FIRED FROM
AMERICANS FOR PROSPERITY.
HE DISCUSSES HOW HE WAS CALLED
THE "N" WORD AND ALL OF THESE
HORRIBLE NAMS AND DESCRIBED HOW
THEY RUINED HIS EQUIPMENT.
LISTEN TO THIS.
>> WHAT HAPPENED?
WALK US THROUGH WHAT HAPPENED
THE OTHER DAY WHEN THEY
COLLAPSED THAT TENT?
>> WELL, I SET UP AROUND 10:00
A.M.
EVERYTHING WAS GOING PRETTY
GOOD.
10:30, I STARTED TO SERVE
HOTDOGS.
AND I WAS PROBABLY 11:30, MAYBE
A QUARTER TO 12, TWO GUYS CAME
IN, ONE HAD A -- LIKE A
HALLOWEEN DEVIL'S MASK ON.
THE OTHER ONE HAD A SKI MASK ON.
BUT I THOUGHT IT WAS A PRANK,
EVERYBODY WAS HAVING FUN.
BUT ANYWAY, SO I GAVE THEM A
HOTDOG.
EVERYBODY HAD TO HAVE A TICKET.
SO THEY HAD TICKETS.
SO I GAVE THEM A HOTDOG H. THEY
GOT THROUGH EATING THEIR HOTDOG,
THEY WENT TO THE RIGHT AND
TURNED OVER THE -- [INAUDIBLE]
AND THE PROTESTERS WERE TEARING
THE TENT DOWN.
SO THE GROUNDSKEEPER, HE CAME IN
AND SAID, CLINT, YOU HAVE TO GET
OUT OF HERE.
THEY ARE TEARING THE TENT DOWN.
>> SEAN: ALL RIGHT.
I MEAN, THEN THEY CALLED HIM THE
"N" WORD, RIGHT TO HIS FACE.
REACTION?
WHY DIDN'T THE MEDIA COVER THAT?
>> I THINK YOUR VIEWERS NEED TO
THINK ABOUT TWO THINGS.
ONE IS, REMEMBER THE HUNDREDS OF
STORIES THAT WE HAVE WATCHED
SINCE 2009 ABOUT THE MENACING
NATURE OF THE TEA PARTY AND ALL
THE ACCUSATIONS MADE ABOUT THE
TEA PARTY.
NEVER MIND THAT THERE WAS NO
EVIDENCE EVER TO BACK UP THE "N"
WORD WITH THE TEA PARTY OR GABBY
GIFFORDS OR THE BATMAN SHOOTING
IN COLORADO, ALL OF THESE THINGS
THAT WERE ATTRIBUTED TO THE TEA
PARTY.
NONE OF IT WAS TRUE.
THIS IS A MEDIA WAS OBSESSIVE
ABOUT THE NEED FOR CIVILITY IN
THE AMERICAN PUBLIC
CONSERVATION.
OKAY.
NOW THE TABLES ARE TURNED AND
HAVE YOU OUTRIGHT VIOLENCE --
AND--
>>> AND RACISM.
>> YOU KNOW, BASICALLY, SEAN,
WHAT IS KEY HERE IS THAT
REPORTERS WERE THERE.
THAT SCENE IS CRAWLING WITH
JOURNALISTS.
THEY ARE ALL THERE.
THEY ARE SEEING IT WITH THEIR
OWN EYES.
IT IS NOT LIKE THEY MISSED THE
STORY AND NOBLE -- NOBODY TOLD
THEM ABOUT T. THEY WERE THERE
AND THEY SAW IT.
STILL, THEY WITHHELD IT FROM THE
PUBLIC.
>> SEAN: SO THERE WAS NO
REFERENCE IN THE MAINSTREAM
MEDIA TO THE VIOLENCE THAT
OCCURRED.
YOU RIGHTLY POINT OUT THAT THEY
WERE THERE.
WE DECIDED TO GO BACK AND WE DID
A SEARCH.
YOU HAVE 100% PEACEFUL MOVEMENT,
KNOWN AS THE TEA PARTY.
THEY SEARCHED HIGH AND LOW.
THEY CONED FIND RACISM OR
VIOLENCE.
THAT'S NOT HOW THEY PORTRAYED
IT.
LISTEN TO THIS.
>> A YEAR-LONG DEBATE THAT HAS
BEEN RANCOROUS AND MEAN FROM THE
START, TURNED EVEN NASTIER
YESTERDAY.
DEMONSTRATORS, PROTESTING THE
BILL, POURED INTO THE HALLS OF
CONGRESS, SHOUTING KILL THE BILL
AND MADE IN THE USSR.
>> OPPONENTS OF THE BILL HAVE
BEEN OUT TODAY.
SOME OF THEM PULLED OUT ALL THE
STOPS, PROTESTERS, ROAMING
WASHINGTON, YELLING SLURS AND
EPITHETS.
>>  WHEN HAMAS OR BEZ BOLA DOES
IT, IT'S CALLED TERRORISM.
WHY SHOULD REPUBLICAN LAWMAKERS
ON BEHALF OF THE HEALTH CARE
INDUSTRY BE VIEWED ANY
DIFFERENTLY, ESPECIALLY NOW THAT
FAR TOO MANY TEA PARTY
PROTESTERS ARE CALLING PRESIDENT
OBAMA AND THE HEALTH CARE REFORM
TO HITLER AND THE HOLOCAUST.
>> SEAN: MEAN, YELLING, SLURS
AND EPITHETS, WHICH THEY COULD
NOT PRODUCE BECAUSE THERE WAS A
$1 HUNDRED,000 REWARD.
>> IT'S TIME FOR THE TEA
PARTY --IME SERIOUS -- TO
CONSIDER DEMSTRAIGDZS IN FRONT
OF NBC AND IN FRONT OF ABC AND
THE NEW YORK TIMES, NEVER MIND
THE MALL.
GO TO THE NETWORKS.
IT IS TIME FOR THERE TO BE A
NATIONAL OUTRAIN AGAINST WHAT
THEY ARE DOING.
>> SEAN: THANKS FOR BEING WITH
US.
WHEN WE COME BACK.
THERE IS A FAMILY THAT NEEDS
YOUR HELP.
THIS MARINE IS BEING HELD RIGHT
NOW AND HE HAS BEEN SINCE AUGUST
IN A MEXICAN PRISON.
HE TRIED TO LEGALLY REGISTER AN
ANTIQUE RIFLE.
HE WAS EN ROUTE TO COSTA REEK A.
HE HAS BEEN LOCKED UP FOUR
MONTHS.
MEXICAN AUTHORITIES REFUSE TO
RELEASE HIM.
HIS PARENTS JOIN ME NEXT.
YOU CAN HELP THEM.
THE LAST MIN.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME R CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
You know how painful heartburn
can be.
For fast, long lasting relief,
use doctor recommended
Gaviscon®.
Only Gaviscon® forms a
protective barrier that helps
block stomach acid from
splashing up-
relieving the pain quickly.
Try fast, long lasting
Gaviscon®.
THE RED CROSS WAS DOWN HERE
ALL THE TIME.
[ man ]
THEY'VE GIVEN US A LOT OF HEART.
IN TIMES OF NEED, THEY'RE THERE.
♪
[ Kerry ] MY DAD WAS WATCHING
HIS HOUSE BURN.
HE TURNED AROUND,
AND ALL OF A SUDDEN, THERWAS
THIS GUY STANDING THERE
FROM THE RED CROSS.
AT A POINT WHERE I HAD
JUST LOST EVERYTHING,
THE IDEA THAT THERE WAS
SOMEONE THERE...
THAT'S AN AMAZING THING.
♪
>> SEAN: NOW A ROAD TRIP TURNED
INTO A NIGHTMARE FOR A BRAVE
MARINE WHO BRIEFLY SERVED IN
BOTH AFGHANISTAN AND IRAN.
HERE'S WHAT HAPPENED,
27-YEAR-OLD JOHN HAMMER WAS
EN ROUTE TO COSTA RICA FOR A
SURFING TRIP TO HELP DEAL WITH
HIS POST TRAUMATIC STRESS
DISORDER WHEN HE WAS CAUGHT WITH
AN ANTIQUE SHOTGUN.
HE WAS TOLD THAT WHEN HE CROSSES
THE BORDER, HE SHOULD REGISTER
IT IN MEXICO.
BUT THIS TURNED OUT NOT TO BE
THE CASE O. AUGUST 20, WHEN HE
TRIED TO REGISTER THE GUN,
LEGALLY, WHEN HE CROSSED THE
BOARD -- BORDER, HE WAS ARRESTED
AND CHARGED WITH CARRYING A
DEADLY WEAPON AND THROWN IN
JAIL.
NOW, HERE IT IS, FOUR MONTHS
LATER, HE IS STILL SITTING IN A
NOTORIOUSLY DANGEROUS PRISON AND
UNTIL A COUPLE OF DAYS AGO, HE
WAS CHAINED TO A BED.
AND HIS PARENTS HAVE BEEN TOLD
THAT THEY WOULD KILL HIS SON
UNLESS THEY WIRE THOUSANDS OF
DOLLARS TO AN ACCOUNT.
THEY ARE DEMANDING THAT THEIR
SON BE RELEASED AND YOU MIGHT BE
ABLE TOO HELP THEM.
HERE ARE THE PATIENTS, OLIVIA
AND JOHN.
THANK YOU BOTH FOR BEING HERE.
>> THANK YOU FOR HAVING US.
>> SEAN: HE SERVED IN ISCPRAK
AFGHANISTAN.
HAS PTSD.
HE TRIED TO GET HELP, GOING ON
VACATION.
HE GETS TO THE AMERICAN BORDER.
HE TELLS THEM HE HAS THE GUN,
RIGHT, OLIVIA?
>> RIGHT.
>> SEAN: OKAY.
>> HE DISCLOSED IT WITH THE U.S.
CUSTOMS SIDE.
THEY TOOK PICTURES AND WEIGHED
IT AND THEY GAVE HIM A
REGISTRATION PAPER TO TAKE TO
THE MEX CONCUSTOMS.
>> SEAN: HE IS SUPPOSED TO HAND
THAT TO THE MEXICAN OFFICIALS AS
HE WAS TOLD TO DO.
IS THAT WHAT HAPPENED?
>> RIGHT.
>> SEAN: OKAY.
WHAT HAPPENS NEXT?
>> HE WAS IMMEDIATELY ARRESTED.
THEY DECLARED THE WEAPON AND HE
WAS IMMEDIATELY ARRESTED?
HE IS DECLARING THE WEAPON, NOT
LIKE HE IS TRYING TO SMUGGLE
THIS THING INTO MEXICO.
THEY ARREST HIM.
THIS IS BACK IN AUGUST!
WHAT HAPPENED SINCE THEN?
AND WHAT IS THE STATUS, HOW CAN
WE HELP GET YOUR SON HOME BY
CHRISTMAS?
>> AFTER THEY ARRESTED HIM... HE
GOT A CALL FROM THE U.S.
CONSULATE THAT HE HAD BEEN
ARRESTED.
THEN, A COUPLE OF DAYINGS AFTER
THAT, HE GOT A CALL FROM SOMEONE
WHO SAID, THIS IS NOT ABOUT THE
POLICE... WE HAVE YOUR SON... IF
YOU DON'T WIRE $1800 TO A
WESTERN UNION ACCOUNT, WE ARE
GOING TO KILL HIM.
HERE HE IS.
THIS IS -- LISTEN TO HIM.
TALK TO HIM.
AND SO, WE TALKED TO HIM.
AND WE SAID, HOW?
WE DON'T -- I DON'T KNOW -- I AM
NOT SURE ABOUT WESTERN UNION.
HE SAID, WE WILL CALL YOU BACK
WITH AN ACCOUNT NUMBER.
>> SEAN: THIS CORRUPTION HAD TO
BE HAPPENING WITHIN THE MEXICAN
JAIL.
>> THAT WAS INSIDE -- IT WAS
INSIDE THE PRISON, YES,
BECAUSE -- THEN WE CALLED THE
CONSULATE AND TOLD THEM WHAT WAS
GOING ON, AS WE ARE TRYING TO
FIGURE OUT THE WESTERN UNION
ACCOUNT NUMBER.
AND THEY SAID, WELL, WE ARE ON
IT.
WE ARE GOING TO CALL THE PRISON
OFFICIALS AND GET TO THE BOTTOM
OF IT AND HAVE HIM ISOLATED.
>> SEAN: OLIVIA, I KNOW THAT
BARACK OBAMA DOESN'T REALLY
LISTEN TO ME.
BUT THIS MIGHT BE AN OPPORTUNITY
FOR HIM TO STEP UP, TELL THE
MEXICAN GOVERNMENT, RELEASE THIS
KID.
AN AMERICAN HERO, WHO HAS BEEN
SUFFERING IN THIS PRISON SINCE
AUGUST.
WHAT'S THE STATUS AND HOW CAN
PEOPLE HELP YOU?
>> WE ARE JUST ASKING FOR
EVERYONE TO TALK TO THEIR
LAWMAKERS.
>> MEAN EYE WOULD MAKE A
PERSONAL PLEA TO THE PRESIDENT
TO CONTACT, YOU KNOW, THIS NEW
INCOMING PRESIDENT ENRIQUE OF
MEXICO AND JUST ASK HIM TO
RESOLVE THIS CASE AND SEND HIM
HOME.
THIS HAS GONE ON TOO LONG.
IT'S A RIDICULOUS CASE.
I THINK THEY KNOW IT'S A
RIDICULOUS CASE.
BECAUSE IT WAS AN ACCIDENT.
IT IS A CASE THAT THEY ARE --
THEIR OWN MILITARY HAS SENT
LETTERS TO THE JUDGE AND IT IS
PROSECUTORS SAYING THIS GUN IS
WANT ON THE RESTRICTED LIST THAT
IS TRYING TO RESTRICT, YOU KNOW
ASSAULT RIFLE, ESSENTIALLY.
THEY ARE AKING, THIS ISN'T
ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
AND THE PROSECUTORS AND THE
JUDGES HAVE REFUSED TO CO