BILLOREILLY.COM.
IF YOU MISSED THE KEY POINTS,
YOU WANT TO SEE IT.
IT'S A BIG DEAL TONIGHT.
CHECK IT OUT.
ALSO, WE WOULD LIKE YOU TO SPOUT
OFF ABOUT THE FACTOR FROM
ANYWHERE IN THE WORLD.
O'REILLY@FOXNEWS.COM.
NAME AND TOWN IF YOU WISH TO
OPINE.
WORD OF THE DAY, DO NOT BE A
MISCREANT.
I LOVE THAT WORD.
DO NOT BE A MISCREANT WHEN
WRITING TO THE FACTOR.
THANKS FOR WATCHING US TONIGHT.
I AM BILL O'REILLY.
PLEASE REMEMBER THAT THE SPIN
STOPS HEREOK BECAUSE WE ARE
DEFINITELY LOOKING OUT FOR YOU.
>> SEAN: THIS IS A FOX NEWS
>> Sean: THIS IS A FOX NEWS
ALERT.
SUSAN RICE,S. THE U.S. AMBASSADR
TO THE UNITED NATIONS WITHDREW
HER NAME FOR CONSIDERATION TO BE
THE L NEXT SECRETARY OF STATE.
IN A LETTER FRONTAL BOUNDARY TO,
SHEUN WROTE I AM CONFIDENT I COD
SERVE IN THE ROLE.
HOWEVER, IF NOMINATED, I'M
CONVINCED THAT THE CONFIRMATION
PROCESS WOULD BE LENGTHY,
DISRUPTIVE, AND COSTLY TO YOU
AND TO OUR MOST PRESSING
INTERNATIONAL AND NATIONAL
PRIORITIES.
THE TRADEOFF IS SIMPLY NOT WORTH
IT TO OUR COUNTRY.
THIS COMES IN THE. WAKE OF
REPUBLICAN LAWMAKERS EXPRESSING
OPPOSITION TO HER NOMINATION
BECAUSE OF COMMENTS SHE MADE
AFTER FOUR AMERICANS WERE KILLED
IN A BLATANT TERRORIST ATTACK IN
BENGHAZI.
NOW AMBASSADOR RICE FIVE DAYS
LATER BLAMED ALL THE VIOLENCE ON
A YouTUBE VIDEO WHEN ALL THE
EVIDENCE SHOWED IT WAS NOT TRUE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA RESPONDED TO THE
LETTER AND SAID THE ATTACKS ON
AMBASSADOR RICE HAVE BEEN UNFAIR
AND MISLEADING.
IN TYPICAL FASHION, THE MEDIA
JUMPED IN, NBC NEWS
SPECIFICALLY, TO RICE'S DEFENSE,
CONTINUED THEI
R FALSE NARRATIVE
THAT ANY CRITICISM OF HER IS NOT
ROOTED IN HER FALSE TESTIMONY
ABOUT RACISM.
ANOTHER DOG WHISTLE.
WATCH THIS.
>> I THINK THIS HAS BECOME AN
IMPOSSIBLE CHALLENGE FOR HER TO
BE CONFIRMED, THAT SHE REALIZED
THAT.
THE WHITE HOUSE REALIZED IT AS
WELL.
I THINK THEY KNOW THEY ARE ON
GOOD POLITICAL SOLID GROUND AS
YOU WERE JUST POINTING OUT.
THIS IS NOT GOING TO BE -- THIS
WON'T HELP REPUBLICANS AT ALL,
THE FACT THAT A WOMAN AND A
WOMAN OF COLOR HAS BEEN FORCED
OUT OF A CONFIRMATION PROCESS
EVEN BEFORE SHE WAS NOMINATED.
>> Sean: JOINING ME WITH
REACTION, FORMER SPEAKER OF THE
HOUSE NEWT GINGRICH.
HOW ARE YOU?
>> I'M DOING VERY, VERY WELL.
I COULDN'T HELP BUT SMILE JUST
NOW AT THAT ABSURDITY.
THE REPUBLICAN PARTY DID
NOMINATE COLIN PAWL WH COLIN POE
SECRETARY OF STATE.
THEY D NOMINATED CONDOLEEZA RICE
WHO BECAME SECRETARY OF STATE.
ON THOSE GROUNDS IT'S HARD TO
COME BACK AND SAY THAT THE
SENATORS WHO HT AD PROBLEMS WERE
DOING SO FOR EITHER RACIAL OR
SEXUAL REASONS.
THEY CLEARLY HAVE PROVEN IN THE
A WILLINGNESS TO WORK WITH
AFRICAN-AMERICANS O, BOTH MALE D
FEMALE.
I ACTUALLY THINK IT WOULD NOT BE
A BAD IDEA FOR PRESIDENT OBAMA
TO SERIOUSLY CONSIDER SEEING IF
PCOLIN POWELL WOULD COME OUT OF
RETIREMENT.
COLIN DID ENDORSET HIM.
THAT MIGHT BE A BI-PARTISAN STEP
THAT WOULD MOVE US IN A
DIRECTION OF A DIFFERENT KIND OF
DIALOGUE THAN WE'RE GOING TO GET
IF WE STAY WITH KIND OF LEFT
WING POLICIES.
>> Sean: THE EVIDENCE WAS
OVERWHELMING.
IT WAS INCONTROVERTIBLE IN THIS
PARTICULAR CASE.
THE CAMPAIGN NEVER STOPS FOR THE
DEMOCRATS.
THERE'S NO TIME FOR ANY
GOVERNING HEREE  WHATSOEVER.
IT SEEMS THAT THEY WANT TO
HUMILIATE, CRUSH, DIVIDE AND
HURT THE REPUBLICAN PARTY.
AM I WRONG AS I OBSERVE THE
FISCAL CLIFF AND ALL OF THESE
ATTACKS THAT A EVER END, WAR ON
WOMEN NEVER ENDS?
>> YOU KNOW, I WAS A BIG FAN AND
VERY, VERY IMPRESSED WITH COACH
WOODEN'S USE OF THE FULL COURT
PRESS AT UCLA.
ONE OF THE MOST REMARKABLE
BASKETBALL DYNASTIES IN HISTORY,
AND IF YOU'RE GOING TO PLAY
AGAINST A FULL COURT PRESS, YOU
BETTER LEARN TO RUN A FULL COURT
PRESS.
IT IS AN OBJECTIVE FACT WE NOW
LIVE IN AN AGE WHERE A CHICAGO
STYLE MACHINE IS TRYING TO
ESTABLISH A PERMANENT 24-HOUR A
DAY, 365 DAYS A YEAR CAMPAIGN,
AND WE JUST BETTER LEARN HOW TO
COPE WITH IT AND HOW TO BE
INVOLVED WITH IT.
THE FACT IS IN THE CASE OF
AMBASSADOR RICE, SHE IS THE
PERSON WHO HAS A GRAVES WIT GRIH
THE PRESIDENT.
SHE WAS SENT OUT BY THE
PRESIDENT TO SAY THINGS THAT
WERE FAL
SE.
SHE WAS USED FOR FIVE SHOWS ON
ONE SUNDAY TO TELL THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE SOMETHING THAT WAS NOT
TRUE.
I THINK IF SHE HAS COMPLAINT
WITH ANYBODY, IT OUGHT TO BE
WITH PRESIDENT OBAMA WHO SENT
HER OU ST THERE, USING HER
POLITICALLY EVEN THOUGH SHE WAS
THE UN AMBASSADOR.
>> Sean: YOU ALWAYS HAVE AN
INTERESTING TAKE ON THE EVENTS
OF THE DAY, SO WE HAVE ALL OF
THESE INCIDENTS OF VIOLENCE THAT
HAVE OCCURRED, OCCUPY, WE SEE
THE LEFT AT THESE G-20 SUMMITS.
NOW WE SAW STEPHEN CROWDER WHO
WORKS HERE PUNCHED IN THE FACE,
A TENT KNOCKED DOWN.
I WANT TO GET YOUR TAKE ON ALL
OF THIS BECAUSE THE SILENCE FROM
PRESIDENT CIVILITY IS DEAFENING
HERE.
THEY ARE HIS ALLIES AND HE HAS
SOME SWAY WITH THEM.
>> IN A NUMBER OF CASES,
PARTICULARLY WITH THREATS OF
VIOLENCE IN MICHIGAN, I HOPE THE
GOVERNOR OF MICHIGAN WOULD CALL
ON THE PRESIDENT TO ASK HIS
ALLIES TO BEHAVE IN A CIVIL AND
DECENT MANNER.
THERE'S NO JUSTIFICATION FOR
PEOPLE THREATENING VIOLENCE.
I THINK ONE OF THE DEMOCRATIC
STATE SENATORS IN MICHIGAN SAID
THAT THEREAI WILL BE BLOOD.
WHAT KIND OF COMMENT IS THAT
FROM AN ELECTED OFFICIAL AND WHY
IS IT BEING TOLERATED?
I ALWAYS THINK THE NETWORKS AND
THE NEW YORK SOMETIMES AND
OTHERS HAVE A REAL OBLIGATION TO
COVER UNION VIOLENCE WHEN IT
OCCURS AND NOT HIDE IT.
I THINK YOU'RE RAISING A GOOD
POINT.
IT'S ONE THAT WE SHOULD BE
AGGRESSIVE IN DEMANDING THAT THE
PRESIDENT CALL ON HIS ALLIES TO
EXERCISE DISCIPLINE AND
CIVILITY.
>> Sean: DO YOU REMEMBER DURINGY
THE TEA PARTY RALLIES?
YOU WERE SPEAKING ABOUT THE S
MEDIA.
THE MEDIA WOULD SEARCH HIGH AND
LOW AND THEY WOULD BE LOOKING
FOR SOMETHING NEGATIVE THAT THE
TEA PARTY MOVEMENT WAS SAYING,
AND USUALLY THERE WERE KIDS ON
THEIR DADS' SHOULDERS AND THEY'D
HEAR PATRIOTIC SPEECHES AND SAY
THE PLEDGE OF ALLEGIANCE AND GOD
BLESS AMERICA AND LEAVE THE
PLACE CLEANER THAN WHEN THEY
FOUND IT.
I ASK YOU THROUGH THIS PRISM AS
THEY COMPARE THIS TO THE TEA
PARTY.
THERE WAS A VENDOR IN THE TENT,
A HOT DOG GUY, BEEN WORKING
THERE FOR 16 YEARS.
I INTERVIEWED THIS MAN ON MY
RADIO PROGRAM.
THEY RUINED HIS EQUIPMENT,
KNOCKED OVER HIS FOOD, AND WELL,
LET ME PLAY THE REST FOR YOU.
>> THEY TRAMPLED THE TENT AND
EVERYTHING IR HAD.
THEY WERE UNDER THE TENT,
TABLES.
HOT DOG BUNS, CHILI, ALL MY
UTENSILS, AND THEN THEY WERE
SAYING LIKE OKAY, MAKE A CHILI
DOG NOW.
EVERYTHING'S ON THE GROUND.
THEY CALLED ME THE N WORD.
THEY CALLED ME SCUM.
YOU'RE ON THE WRONG SIDE, AND
LIKE I SAID TO THEM, SEAN, THAT
I WAS THERE TO DO A JOB.
PROSPERITY HIRED ME TO DO A JOB
TO SELL HOT DOGS.
I'M NOT HERE AND I'M NOT ON THAT
SIDE.
I'M JUST HERE.
SO IT REALLY DIDN'T MAKE A
DIFFERENCE TO THOSE GUYS.
>> Sean: YOU WERE HIRED TO DO A
JOB, AND THEY PURPOSELY STARTED
DESTROYING YOUR EQUIPMENT,
CALLING YOU THE N WORD AND UNCLE
TOM?
GO AHEAD.
>> THEY DIDN'T CARE.
THEY DIDN'T CARE.
>> Sean: THE MEDIA DIDN'T COVER
THET VIOLENCE.
IF THIS WAS A TEA PARTY RALLY,
WHAT WOULD THE REACTION BE IN
TH TE MEDIA?
>> WELL, I MEAN YOU KNOW WHAT IT
WOULDOU BE.
THIS AGAIN IS PART OF THE TOTAL
BIAS OF THE MODERN MEDIA IN
PROTECTING THE LEFT EVERY WAY IT
CAN.
I WOULD HOPE THAT A COUPLE
CONSERVATIVE LAWYERS LISTENING
TO THAST ON YOUR RADIO SHOW TODY
WOULD GO TO HIM AND OFFER TO
REPRESENT HIM PRO BONO AND FILE
A SUIT FOR DAMAGES AGAINST THE
PEOPLE BECAUSE I SUSPECT THERE
ARE PICTURES OF WHO THEY ARE.
I SUSPECT THAT THEY'RE
VULNERABLE TO BEING SUED, AND I
THINK WE NEED TO USE TO LEARN
THEE LEFT'S OWN TECHNIQUES
AGAINST IT.
I THINK WE'VE GOT TO BE MUCH
MORE AGGRESSIVE IN RAISING THE
ISSUE OF VIOLENCE ON THE LEFT
AND IN DEMANDING THAT IT BE
POLICED, THAT PEOPLE BE ARRESTED
WHEN NECESSARY, AND THAT THE
PRESIDENT HAS A ROLE TO PLAY
HERE IN CALLING ON HIS OWN
ALLIES TO EXERCISE RESTRAINT AND
TO BE DISCIPLINED AND RECOGNIZE
THE RULE OF LAW.
>> Sean: HOW DO YOU INTERPRET
OCCUPY, THIS LABOR VIOLENCE, THE
G-20 SUMMIT?
HOW DO YOU INTERPRET THAT COMING
FROM THE LEFANT AND THE LANGUAGE
FROM THE LEFT WHICH NEITHER YOU
OR I WOULD EVER GET AWAY WITH?
>> I THINK THAT WHAT YOU HAVE IS
A MOVEMENT ON OFFENSE WHICH IS
DESPERATELY TRYING TO CHANGE
AMERICA AND TRYING TO BROW BEAT
AND RIDICULE AND INTIMIDATE THE
REST OF US INTO PUTTING UP WITH
ANTI-DEMOCRATIC OPPRESSION BY
VERY MILITANT SMALL GROUPS.
I THINK WE HAVE TO PROVE WHEN
NECESSARY THAT WE'LL USE THE
POLICE, WE'RE PREPARED WHEN
NECESSARY TO FILE LAWSUITS, AND
WE'RE GOING TO GO - AFTER THEM.
>> Sean: THESE ARE TWO BIG
LOSSES FOR THE PRESIDENT.
I T MEAN, THE PRESIDENT, BIG
SUPPORTER OF BIG LABOR, WENT
THERE THE DAY BEFORE, AND THEN
THE LEGISLATURE, YOU KNOW,
PASSED RIGHT TO WORK WHICH, BY
THE WAY, ENDS LEGALIZED
STEALING.
I'M NOT TALKING ABOUT
RANK-AND-FILE MEMBERS.
I'M TALKING ABOUT UNION
LEADERSHIP.
THEY SHOULDN'T BEBO SPENDING
RANK-AND-FILE MONEY ON POLITICAL
CAMPAIGNS AND THEN SUSAN RICE.
THE PRESIDENT TRIED TO STAND UP
FOR HER BUT THAT DIDN'T WORK,
EITHER.
AS IT WE INTERPRET THAT
RELATES TO NEGOTIATIONS WITH THE
PRESIDENT?
>> WELL, LOOK.
I THINK NEGOTIATIONS IS ANOTHER
TOPIC WE'LL TALK ABOUT, BUT I
WOULD SAY WHAT WE'RE SEEING IS
THE NATURAL BALANCE OF THINGS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WON A VICTORY.
IT WAS A BIG VICTORY.
IT WAS AN IMPRESSIVE VICTORY.
I DIDN'T THINK HE COULD DO IT.
HAVING WON THAT VICTORY, NOW
WE'RE BACK TO REALITY.
THE LONG TERM TREND IN AMERICA
TOWARDS GREATER PRODUCTIVITY,
LESS UNIONISM, PUBLIC REACTION
AGAINST EXULSR COMPULSORY UNIOND
AMBASSADOR RICE MISLED THE
ENTIRE COUNTRY IN PUBLIC AND SHE
COULDN'T WITHSTAND THE SCRUTINY
OF LYING TO THE AMERICAN PEOPLE.
>> Sean: WHEN WE COME BACK, SOME
OF HIS BEST FRIENDS THAT LECTURE
US ON THE NEED TO RAISE TAXES.
THEY'REER FINDING TAX SHELTERS N
PLACES LIKE BERMUDA.
ONE OF THEM
IS WARREN BUFFETT.
WE'LL CONTINUE WITH FORMER
SPEAKER NEWT GINGRICH.
>>> WOULD YOU GET YOUR JOB BACK
IF YOU WERE CAUGHT SMOKING A
LITTLE WEED AT WORK AND
DRINKING?
THES MEN DID ANTHESE MEN DID ANN
HELPED THEM.
THAT'S COMING UP NEXT.
LET'S GIVE THANKS -
FOR AN IDEA.
A GRAND IDEA CALLED AMERICA.
THE IDEA THAT
IF YOU WORK HARD,
IF YOU HAVE A DREAM,
IF YOU WORK WITH
YOUR NEIGHBORS...
YOU CAN DO MOST ANYTHING.
THIS LED TO OTHER IDEAS
LIKE LERTY
AND ROCK 'N' ROLL.
TO FREE MARKETS,
FREE ENTERPRISE,
AND FREE REFILLS.
IT PUT A MAN ON THE MOON
AND A PHONE IN YOUR POCKET.
OUR COUNTRY'S GONE THROUGH A LOT
OVER THE CENTURIES AND A HALF.
BUT THIS IDEA ISN'T FRAGILE.
WHEN TIMES GET TOUGH,
IT RALLIES US AS ONE.
EVEAND WHEN THEY DO,LE
BELTHE DREAM COMES TRUE.
WE'RE GRATEFUL
TO BE A PART OF IT.
>> SEAN: YOU MAY BE SHOCKED TO
>> Sean: YOU MAY BE SHOCKED TO
LEARN THAT ONE OF PRESIDENT
OBAMA'S SUPPORTERS IS NOT PAYING
HIS FAIR SHARE IN TAXES.
I'M TALKING ABOUT THE EXECUTIVE
CHAIRMAN OF GOOGLE, ERIC
SCHMIDT.
HIS NET WORTH RUMORED TO BE
APPROACHING $8 BILLION,
ACCORDING TO FORBES MAGAZINE,
AND DESPITE BEING AN OBAMA DONOR
AND SERVING ON THE PRESIDENT'S
COUNCIL OF ADVISORS ON SCIENCE
AND TECHNOLOGY, MR. SCHMIDT IS
ONE OF THOSE LIBERALS THAT FALLS
INTO THE CATEGORY OF DO AS I
SAY, NOT AS I DO.
HERE'S WHY.
IN RECENT DAYS HIS COMPANY,
GOOGLE, HAS MADE HEADLINES FOR,
WELL, NOT EXACTLY PAYING THEIR
FAIR SHARE.
ITY TURNS OUT THAT SCHMIDT AT TE
HELM OF THE COMPANY WHEN
ACCORDING TO A REPORT BY
BLOOMBERG NEWS, COUL GOOGLE AVOD
ABOUT $2 BILLION IN WORLDWIDE
INCOME TAXES IN 2011 BY SHIFTING
9.8 BILLION DOLLARS IN REVENUES
INTO A BERMUDA SHELL COMPANY,
ALMOST DOUBLE THE TOTAL FROM
THREE YEARS BEFORE ACCORDING TO
FILINGS.
NOW, WHILE THE REPORT NOTES THAT
THE MONEY WAS MOVED AROUND
LEGALLY, THIS SEEMS LIKE A
DIRECT CONTRADICTION TO
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S NON-STOP
LECTURES ABOUT CORPORATE GREED
AND PAYING YOUR FAIR SHARE.
MR. SCHMIDT HAS SINCE RESPONDED
TO THE CONTROVERSY SAYING HE'S,
QUOTE, PROUD OF HIS TAX MOVES.
EVEN MORE INTERESTING,
MR. SCHMIDT WANTS RUMORED TO BET
THE TOP OF THE PRESIDENT'S
CABINET RECRUITING CLASS FOR A
SECOND TERM.
ALTHOUGH S HE PREEMPTIVELY
DECLINED SUCH AN OFFER, SOME
POSITIONS THROWN AROUND WERE
TREASURY OR THE
SECRETARY OF BUSINESS.
HERE WE HAVE THE PRESIDENT'S
BILLIONAIREHE BUDDY AT GOOGLE
HELPING TO SHELTER HIS MONEY IN
A SHELL COMPANY IN BERMUDA IN
ORDER TO AVOID PAYING HIS FAIR
SHARE AND BEING OFFERED A
CABINET POST.
NOT ONLY THAT, WARREN BUFFETT,
HAS A PIECEINE
ABOUT HIM.
MASSIVE AMOUNTS OF TAX DOLLARS
HE'S NOT PAYING BECAUSE HE'S
USING EVERY LOOP HOLE IMAGINABLE
NOT TO PAY.
A LITTLE IRONIC, HUH?
>>IT I THINK THE HOUSE REPUBLICS
OUGHT TO PASS THE GOOGLE BUFFETT
TAX BILL PROVIDED THAT EVERY
AMERICAN SHOULD HAVE ACCESS TO
AT LEAST AS MANY DEDUCTIONS AND
LOOPHOLES AS WARREN BUFFETT AND
ERIC SCHMIDT.
WE SHOULD TAKE ADVANTAGE OF
LIBERALS BEING HUMAN AND TRYING
TO PROTECT THEMSELVES AND SIMPLY
SUGGEST THAT EVERYBODY ELSE
OUGHT TO HAVE THE SAME RIGHT.
THAT SHOULD BE PART OF OUR
ANSWER TO PRESIDENT OBAMA'S
CONSTANT DEMAND FOR HIGHER
TAXES.
THESE ARE HIS ALLIES.
THEY CLEARLY ARE DOING WHAT THEY
THINK WHAT IS LEGAL AND IT IS
LEGAL.
WE SHOULD EXTEND THAT LEGALITY
TO THE MIDDLE CLASS.
IT WOULD BE VERY EDUCATIONAL TO
SUDDENLY CALL A HEARING AND ASK
BUFFETT TO COME IN AND EDUCATE
THE WHOLE COUNTRY ON HOW THE
MIDDLE CLASS CAN USE EVERY LOOP
HOLE TO AVOID PAYING TAXES.
>> Sean: BY THE WAY, 36 OF
PRESIDENTSI OBAMA'S EXECUTIVE
OFFICE STAFF, THEY 0 TH OWE THE
COUNTRY $833 IN BACK TAXES.
FEDERAL EMPLOYEES OWE BILLIONS
IN UNPAID TAXES.
WHY IF THAT WAS YOU OR ME,
HANDCUFFED, PERP WALKED, MADE A
MODEL CITIZEN BEFORE THE NATION.
I THINK THERE WOULD BE A BIT OF
A DOUBLE STANDARD IN HANDLING
SOME OF THAT.
>> WELL, THIS IS A CENTRAL PART
OF THE CONSERVATIVE ARGUMENT
ABOUT BIG GOVERNMENT.
BIG GOVERNMENT'S INHERENTLY
UNFAIR.
IT INHERENTLY HAS ADVANTAGES FOR
ITS FRIENDS.
IT INHERENTLY TAKES CARE OF
INSIDERS CREATING A SYSTEM WHICH
IS THE OPPOSITE OF THE RULE OF
LAW AND IT'S THE OPPOSITE OF A
FREE SOCIETY.
THAT'S WHY CONSERVATIVES
HISTORICALLY HAVE ARGUED FOR
SMALLER GOVERNMENT.
THESE KIND OFES THINGS ARE ALMOT
INEVIDENT ABLE BECAUSE PEOPLE
WHO HAVE POWER TAKE CARE OF
THEMSELVES.
THEY TAKE CARE OF THEIR FRIENDS.
>> Sean: I'VE BEEN WAITING FOR
THE HOUSE LEADERSHIP, THERE'S A
LOT OF IN-FIGHTING GOING ON.
SOME TEA PARTY CONSERVATIVES ARE
CLAIMING THEY'VE BEEN PURGED OF
COMMITTEES FOR CERTAIN T VOTES.
YOU'VE BEEN FOLLOWING THIS.
IN NEGOTIATIONS WITH THE
PRESIDENT, YOU'VE BEEN FOLLOWING
IT.
YOUR ADVICE WAS BETTER THAN
MINE.
I SAID SO AT THE TIME.
YOU SAID PASS A SERIES OF BILLS.
I'VE BEEPAN WAITING.
THEY HAVEN'T DONE THAT YET.
DO YOU THINK THEY STILL HAVE
TIME TO DO THAT?
>> SURE, THEY HAVE TIME TO DO
IT, BUT I THINK THEY'VE BEEN
CAUGHT UP IN A -- I THINK A
LOSING PROPOSITION.
THEY'RE NOT GOING TO GET A REAL
AGREEMENT OUT OF BARACK OBAMA
BEFORE THE EN AD OF THE YEAR.
HE JUST WON AN ELECTION.
HE'SUS FEELING LIKE HE'S DOMINA.
HE HAS WHAT THE JAPANESE USED TO
CALL VICTORY DISEASE.
HE'S MAKING OUTLANDISH
SUGGESTIONS SUCH AS ELIMINATING
THE DEBT CEILING PERMANENTLY SO
THE PRESIDENT CAN RUN UP ANY
LEVEL OF DEFICIT HE WANTS TO.
THIS IS A GOOD TIME FOR THE
HOUSE TO PASS -- I WOULD PASS
TWO BILLS.
I'D PASS A COMPLETE EXTENSION OF
EVERY SINGLE TAX CUT AND THEN I
WOULD PASSGL AN EXTENSION OF EVY
TAX CUT EXCEPT THE RATES AT THE
VERY TOP, PASS BOTH OF THEM,
SEND THEM TO THE SENATE AND SAY
WE'RE NOT DEALING WITH ANYTHING
ELSE RIGHT NOW.
WE'RE NOT PLAYING GAMES RIGHT
NOW.
WE WANT TO MAKE SURE THE MIDDLE
CLASS DOESN'T FACE A TAX
INCREASE.
YOU PICK.
YOU PASS SOMETHING, GET IT DONE.
NOW IT'S UP TO THE DEMOCRATS AND
THE SENATE AND THE PRESIDENT.
YOU ARE NOW RESPONSIBLE FOR THE
MIDDLE CLASS TAX INCREASE.
>> I HAVE A NAME FOR THE BILL.
I WANT TO SEE IF YOU CAN COME UP
WITH A BETTER ONE.
I HATE WHEN YOU TOP ME, BUT IF
IT'S BETTER, I GO ALONG WITH A
GOOD IDEA, NOT WHO IS RIGHT.
HOW ABOUT THE STOP STEALING FROM
OUR KIDS AND GRAND KIDS BILL OF
2012?
>> THAT'S THE SPENDING BILL.
THAT COMES NEXT.
>> Sean: NO, NO, NO.
I WANT THAT FIRST.
>> THAT'S MY POINT.
>> Sean: THAT SHOULD BE THE
FIRST ONE.
>> THERE ARE TWO STEPS  HERE.
I THINK IT IS HELPFUL FOR THE
REPUBLICAN PARTY TO MAKE VERY
CLEAR IT DOES NOT WANT TAXES TO
GO UP ON WORKING AMERICANS, AND
I THINK THEY'VE BEEN OUT
MANEUVERED BY OBAMA FOR THE PAST
FEW WEEKS.
THEY NEED TO GET PAST THAT AND
MAKE CLEAR TO EVERYBODY WE DON'T
WANT TAXES TO GO UP FOR THE
MIDDLE CLASS.
SECOND, THEY NEED TO MAKE SURE,
THAT YOU JUST SAID, WE HAVE A
BIG FIGHT OVER OUR CHILDREN AND
GRANDCHILDREN.
THAT STARTS JANUARY 3rd.
>> Sean: ALL RIGHT.
I GUESS WE'LL BE BACK AFTER OUR
CHRISTMAS VACATION AND WE'LL BE
BACK FIGHTING ON THE SAME THING,
BUT MR. SPEAKER, GOOD TO SEE
YOU.
THANK YOU.
>>OU GOOD TO SEE YOU.
>> Sean: COMING UP, THEY WERE
CAUGHTNK ON CAMERA DRINKING AND
SMOKING POT WHILE THEY WERE ON
THEIR LUNCH BREAK.
THEY WERE QUICKLY FIRED BUT
SUDDENLY HAVE THEIR JOBS BACK.
WHAT HAPPENED?
WHERE DID THEY WORK?
WHY DID THEY GET REHIRED, AND
LEFT WING NUT HARRY BELAFONTE
HAS LESS THAN SOUND ADVICE FOR
THE PRESIDENT OBAMA.
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO BELIEVE
WHAT HE THINKS OBAMA SHOULD DO
WITH THE DISSENTERS.
>>> YOU'LL MEET THE FAMILY OF A
BRAVE MARINE AFGHANISTAN IRAQ
WAR HERO WHO IS IN JAIL IN
MEXICO AND HAS BEEN SINCE AUGUST
AND THE OBAMA ADMINISTRATION
HASN'T HELPED HIM YET.
WHY?
UNTIL THE LAST MINUTE.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME R CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
You know how painful heartburn
can be.
For fast, long lasting relief,
use doctor recommended
Gaviscon®.
Only Gaviscon® forms a
protective barrier that helps
block stomach acid from
splashing up-
relieving the pain quickly.
Try fast, long lasting
Gaviscon®.
TIME FOR CITI PRICE REWIND.
BECAUSE YOUR DAUGHTER REALLY
WANTS THAT PINK CASTLE THING.
AND YOU REALLDON'T WANT
TO PAY MORE THAN YOU HAVE TO.
ONLY CITI PRICE REWIND
AUTOMATICALLY SEARCHES
FOR THE LOWEST PRICE.
AND IF IT FINDONE, YOU GET
REFUNDED THE DIFFERENCE.
JUST USE YOUR CITI CARD
AND REGISTER YOUR PURCHASE
ONLINE.
HAVE A SUPER SPARKLY DAY!
OK.
[ Male Announcer ] NOW ALL
YOUEED IS A MAGIC CARRIAGE.
CITI PRICE REWIND.
START SAVING
AT CITI.COM/PRICEREWIND.
TILL YOU FINISH YOUR VEGETABLES.
[ clock ticking ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THERE'S A BETTER WAY...
V8 V-FUSION.
VEGETABLE NUTRITION THEY NEED,
FRUIT TASTE THEY LOVE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
OR...TRY KIDS BOXES!
TIRED OF FEES PILING UP
INTRODUCING CHASE LIQUID.
THE RELOADABLE CARD
WITH NO FEE RELOADS
AND WITHDRAWALS AT CHASE ATMS.
ALL FOR ONE FLAT MONTHLY FEE
SO THERE'S ZERO CONFUSION.
GET RID OF PREPAID PROBLEMS.
GET CHASE LIQUID.
>> Sean: WELCOME BAN TO HANNITY.
ONE MAY THINK THAT DRINKING
ALCOHOL AND SMOKING MARIJUANA ON
THE JOB MAY BE REASON ENOUGH TO
GET FIRED.
THAT'S NOT THE CASE WHEN IT
COMES TO, SURPRISE, SURPRISE,
SOME UNION MEMBERS.
YOU MAY REMEMBER THE DETROIT
AUTO WORKERS WHO WERE FIRED
AFTER BEING CALL THE RED-HANDED
-- CAUGHANT RED-HANDED FOR THEIR
EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES
DURING BREAKS.
AFTER DIGGING THROUGH THEIR
LABOR CONTRACTS, THEY WERE ABLE
TO REVERSE THE DISMISSALS THANKS
TO AN ARBITRATOR YES ARBITRATOR.
IS THIS SYMBOLIC OF WHAT'S
HAPPENING TO THE CITY OF
DETROIT?
IS A LACK OF ACCOUNTABILITY
CONTRIBUTING TO THE CITY HEADING
TO BANKRUPTCY.
OF 563,000 PEOPLE OVER THE AGE
OF 16 WHO ARE ELIGIBLE TO WORK,
250,000 OR 46% DO NOT HAVE A JOB
IN DETROIT.
ININ FACT, THEY AREN'T LOOKING.
IF THAT'S NOT ENOUGH.
OUT OF THE 264,000 HOUSEHOLDS IN
THE CITY, ALMOST 100,000 OF
THEM, 35%, NOW HAVE TO RELY ON
FOOD STAMPS.
JOINING ME NOW WITH REACTION TO
THE DECLINE AND PERHAPS A
PREVIEW OF WHAT MAY BECOME OF
MANY OTHER U.S. INDUSTRIES IN IN
THE COUNTRY, TUCKER CARLSON.
I SPENT OVER A DECADE IN THE
RESTAURANT BUSINESS AND IN THE
CONSTRUCTION BUSINESS, EVERY JOB
IMAGINABLE.
THIS IS NONOTRS ABOUT WORKERS T.
I RESPECT THE HARD WORK.
I DON'T CARE IF PEOPLE JOIN A
UNION.
THEY SHOULDN'T BE FORCED TO IS
MYUL CASE.
WITH THAT SAID, WHEN YOU LOOK AT
A CITY LIKE DETROIT AND A
DECISION LIKE THIS, THEY'RE
SMOKING POT, THEY'RE DRINKING,
HOW DO THEY GET THEIR JOB BACK?
IF I DID THAT, I'M OUTTA HERE.
>> WELL, OBVIOUSLY IT'S
TROUBLING IF WORKERS, WHAT THEY
DO ON THEIR RECREATION TIME
AFFECTS THEIR WORKPLACE.
>> Sean: TAKE A LOOK A ST THIS.
THEY'RE DRINKING HEAVILY,
THEY'RE SMOKING WEED, GOING BACK
TO BUILD OUR CARS.
THAT'S NOT PROBLEMATIC FOR YOU?
>> CONCEPTIONALLY IT'S
PROBLEMATIC NOT KNOWING ANYTHING
MORE THAN WHAT I'M SAYING.
I'M SAID CONCEPTUALLY IT'S
PROBLEMATIC.
THE LARGER PICTURE IS WHAT YOU
STARTED OUT WITH.
THE AMERICAN WORKER IS THE ENVI
OF THE WORLD.
THE AUTOMOTIVE INDUSTRY IS THE
ENVY OF THE WORLD.
I THINK THE PROBLEMS IN THE
WORKPLACE ARE PROBLEMS THAT
DETROIT IS IN A SITUATION THAT
OTHER CITIES HAVE FOUND
THEMSELVES IN.
NEW YORK CITY WAS ON LIFE
SUPPORT AT ONE POINT, BUT IT
CAME BACK.
I THINK THAT THE AMERICAN
WORKERS WILL WORK THROUGH THIS
PERIOD WITH THEIR GOVERNMENT.
>> Sean: TUCKER, THI THEY LOST F
THE POPULATION OF DETROIT.
YOU HEARD THE STATISTICS.
THEY'RE BULLDOZING ENTIRE
NEIGHBORHOODS BECAUSE HALF THE
POPULATION ISON GONE TO SO
CONSOLIDATE SERVICES.
THEY LOST ALL THOSE CAR
MANUFACTURING JOBS.
ARE THE UNIONS PARTLY
RESPONSIBLE?
D LEADERSHIP.
>> OUR AUTO INDUSTRY IS NOT THE
ENVY OF THE WORLD.
I LOVE THIS COUNTRY.
A LOT OF OUR CARS AREN'T VERY
GOOD.
WE'VE HAD OUR LUNCH EATEN BY
FOREIGN CAR MAKERS.
I WORKED IN A UNION FACTORY IN
COLLEGE.
JUST BECAUSE YOU'RE UNION
DOESN'T MEAN YOU'RE A BAD
EMPLOYEE.
IT DOES MEAN, HOWEVER, THAT MANY
BAD EMPLOYEES, MEDIOCRE
EMPLOYEES ARE PROTECTED BY THE
UNION.
THIS IN THE END ONLY HURTS
UNIONS.
THERE'S A REASON THAT DETROIT
WHICH IS ONE OF U THE BIRTHPLACS
OF THE LABOR UNION BECAME A
RIGHT TO WORK STATE THIS WEEK
BECAUSE OF NONSENSE LIKE THIS.
IT'S SELF DISCREDITING FOR
UNIONS TO PROTECT PEOPLE WHO
WORK WITH DANGEROUS HEAVY
MACHINERY WHO ARE GETTING HIGH
ON THEIR BREAKS.
COME ON.
>> EVEN IF YOU ACCEPT THAT
REASONING WHICH I DON'T, BUT IF
YOU DO, IT ISN'T THAT THE
SITUATION IN DETROIT IS GOING TO
LEAD TO THE DECLINE OF AMERICAN
CITIES.
>
>> Sean: WHY CAN'T YOUEC LOOK AT
SOMETHING AS BASICS AS THAT AND
SAY YOU'VE GOT FIRE THOSE GUYS?
THEY DO NOT REFLECT EVERY
WORKER.
AS A MATTER OF FACT, GOOD
WORKERS, THEIR NAME AND
REPUTATION IS HURT BECAUSE OF
SCENES LIKE THIS AND PEOPLE
SEEING THIS.
>> I'M SAYING OWNERSHIP.
THE MANAGEMENT AND OWNERSHIP
ENTERED INTO AN AGREEMENT WITH
THOSE SAME WORKERS AND THE
UNIONS REPRESENTING THEM.
THEY SET UP A PROCESS.
IT DIDN'T WORK OUT.
>> Sean: WHY ARE THERE ALL OF
THESE -- I'LL THROW THIS TO
TUCKER.
LOOK AT MISSISSIPPI AND
TENNESSEE AND ALABAMA OF.
ALL THESE STATES, GUESS WHAT?
NOW THEY'RE BUILDING CARS.
THEY'RE BUILDING CARS IN INDIA
AND OTHER CUPS.
UNIONS DON'T -- SOME UNIONS DO,
BUT A LOT OF UNIONS HAVE SOLD
OUT THEIR OWN WORKERS.
ONE OF THE REASONS YOU SEE
DEPRESSED WAGES IN THE COUNTRY
IS BECAUSE D OF LOW SKILLED
IMMIGRATION WHICH IS SUPPORTED
BY THE UNIONS FOR REASONS THAT
ARE NOT CLEAR AT ALL.
ACTING AGAINST THEIR OWN
INTEREST AT THE BEHEST OF THE
DEMOCRATIC PARTY WHICH THEY ARE
THE MOST FAITHFUL OF GET THE
VOTE OUT.
THEY'RE HURT THEIR OWN
MEMBERSHIP.
>> Sean: WE HAVE THIS VIOLENCE
TAKE PLACE.
YOU SAW THE VIDEO, AND IF IT WAS
A TEA PARTY MEMBER, I TALKED TO
THISLK HOT DOG GUY WHO WILL BE N
GRETA, BY THE WAY, LATER
TONIGHT, AND I JUST PLAYED HIM
WITH NEWT GINGRICH USING THE N
WORD.
THE N WORD WAS USED AGAINST HIM.
HE WAS CALLED AN UNCLE TOM.
HIS EQUIPMENT WAS RUINED.
HIS FOODOD WAS KNOCKED OVER.
IF THIS HAPPENED AT TEA PARTY
RALLY, NOT A LABORALLY, IT WOULT
WOULD BEES FRONT PAGE NEWS.
HOW DOES THIS HAPPEN?
G-20 SUMMIT, VIOLENCE.
LABOR MOVEMENT?
THIS VIOLENT INCIDENT THIS WEEK.
NO PROMINENT LIBERAL SPEAKS OUT.
WHY?
>> I'M A PRODUCT OF THE SOCIAL
JUSTICE MOVEMENT FOR CIVIL
RIGHTS IN THE COUNTRY WHICH WAS
A NON-VIOLENT MOVEMENT.
THOSE WHO CAME OUT FOR VON
VIOLENCE, VIOLENCE WAS VISITED
UPON THEM.
THEY HAVE TO BE PREPARED TO PAY
THE CONSEQUENCE FOR BEING
NON-VIOLENT.
IN THE SAME WAY WHEN PEOPLE
BREAK THE LAW, THEY'VE GOT TO GO
TO JAIL.
NOW, WHETHER THE MEDIA
CRITICIZES THEM --
>> Sean: IF A TEA PARTY MEMBER
USED THE N WORD AGAINST A GUY
THAT'S BEEN SELLING HOT DOGS FOT
--E  NO REPORTS ON ANY MAJOR
NETWORKS.
>> I'M NOT FOR ITJO UNDER ANY
CIRCUMSTANCES, SO I NEVER
CONDONE THE N WORD UNDER ANY
CIRCUMSTANCES.
>> Sean: THEY RUINED HIS
EQUIPMENT.
>> THE OTHER THING THAT WAS
MENTIONED A LITTLE EARLIER THAT
HAS TO BEHAME RESPONDED TO IS TE
ROLE OF UNIONS IN THE COUNTRY.
IN CIVIL RIGHTS, CHILD LABOR
LAWS, WORKPLACE SAFETY AND
OVERTIME PAY.
>> Sean: WAS IT WRONG TO SAY TO
PEOPLE YOU CAPTURE WORK UNLESS
YOU JOIN A UNION, PAY DUES, AND
THAT MONEY IS USED FOR A
POLITICAL PARTY?
>> IF IT GOES THROUGH THE
DEMOCRATIC PROCESSOU AND PASSEDY
ELECTED OFFICIALS AND THE
WORKERS THEMSELF, YES.
>> Sean: SO YOU'RE NOT PRO
CHOICE?
>> I'M P FOR ORGANIZED LABOR.
>> Sean: WOW.
SO W THA FORCE PEOPLE, TAKE THER
MONEY WHETHER THEY LIKONE IT OR
NOT.
>> TO PROTECT THE RIGHTS OF
WORKERS IN AMERICA.
>> Sean: IT'S A LICENSE TO
STEAL.
>> IN EVERY INSENTENCE WHEN
THERE'S REGULATION, THEY GET
ABUSED.
>> Sean: THANKS FOR BEING WITH
US.
STILL AHEAD, WE COUNT THE MANY
WAYS THAT THE MEDIA BIAS IS ON
DISPLAY.
>>> ALSO, HARRY BELAFONTE IS
LOBBING SOME IDIOTIC AND
INCENDIARY COMMENTS.
THIS TIME HE'S OFFERING
PRESIDENT OBAMA SOME ADVICE ON
DEALING WITH THE OPPOSITION AND
YOU WON'T BELIEVE WHAT AN ESPN
ANALYST IS SAYING ABOUT REDSKINS
QUARTERBACK RG-III, ROBERT
GRIFFIN III.
HIS COMMENT WILL MAKE YOUR BLOOD
BOIL.
WE HAVE THE TAPE.
WE'LL PLAY IT STRAIGHT AHEAD
COMING UP.
S.
COPD INCLUDES CHRONIC
BRONCHITIS AND EMPHYSEMA.
SPIRIVA HELPS CONTROL
MY COPD SYMPTOMS
BY KEEPING MY AIRWAYS
OPEN FOR 24 HOURS.
PLUS, IT REDUCES COPD FLARE-UPS.
SPIRIVA IS THE ONLY ONCE-DAILY
INHALED COPD MAINTENANCE
TREATMENT THAT DOES BOTH.
SPIRIVA HANDIHALER TIOTROPIUM
BROMIDE INHALATION POWDER
DOES NOT REPLACE FAST-ACTING
INHALERS FOR SUDDEN SYMPTOMS.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU HAVE
KIDNEY PROBLEMS, GLAUCOMA,
TROUBLE URINATING, OR
AN ENLARGED PROSTATE.
THESE MAY WORSEN WITH SPIRIVA.
DISCUSS ALL MEDICINES
YOU TAKE, EVEN EYE DROPS.
STOP TAKING SPIRIVA AND SEEK
IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
IF YOUR BREATHING
SUDDENLY WORSENS,
YOUR THROAT OR TONGUE
SWELLS, YOU GET HIVES,
VISION CHANGES OR EYE PAIN,
OR PROBLEMS PASSING URINE.
OTHER SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE
DRY MOUTH AND CONSTIPATION.
NOTHING CAN REVERSE COPD
SPIRIVA HELPS ME BREATHE BETTER.
(BLOWING SOU)
ASK YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT SPIRIVA.
Is bigger than we think ...
Sometimelike the flu.fer from
With aches, fever and chills-
the flu's a really big deal.
So why treat it like
it's a little cold?
There's something
that works differently
than over-the-counter
remedies.
Prescription TAMIFLU attacks
the flu virus at its source.
So don't wait. Call your
doctor right away.
TAMIFLU is prescription
medicine for treating the flu
in adults and children
one year and older
whose flu symptoms started
within the last two days.
Before taking TAMIFLU tell your
doctor if you're pregnant,
nursing. have serious
health conditions,
or take other medicines.
If you develop an allergic
reaction, a severe rash,
or signs of unusual behavior,
stop taking TAMIFLU and call
your doctor immediately.
Children and adolescents in
particular may be at an
increased risk
of seizures, confusion
or abnormal behavior.
The most common
side effects are
mild to moderate nausea
and vomiting.
The flu comes on fast,
so ask your
doctor about TAMIFLU.
Prescription for flu.
>> Sean: BACK TO HANNITY.
EVEN THOUGH 59 MILLIONS VOTED
AGAINST PRESIDENT OBAMA ON
ELECTION DAY, HIS SUPPORTERS
CANNOT SEEM TO COMPREHEND WHY
HE'S RECEIVING SUCH OPPOSITION
TO HIS RADICAL LIBERAL JE AGEND.
ONE OF HIS LONG TIME ALLIES,
HARRY BELAFONTE, HAS SOME
DOWNRIGHT DISTURBING ADVICE
ABOUT HOW OBAMA SHOULD DEAL WITH
DISSENTERS.
HE WAS ASKED ABOUT REPUBLICANS
PUSHING REFORM TO THE COUNTRY'S
BROKEN I ENTITLEMENT SYSTEM.
BELIEVE IT OR NOT, THIS IS WHAT
HE SAID.
>> THE AMERICAN PEOPLE IN THEIR
MATURITY DECLARED THEMSELVES
FULLY.
WE WANT WHAT BARACK OBAMA IS
TALKING ABOUT.
WE WANT THE COUNTRY TO GO IN
THAT DIRECTION AND WHAT
FASCINATES ME IS
THAT IN THE
FACE OF MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
EXPRESSING THEIRIC DESIRE, THE
WHOLE POLITICAL ESTABLISHMENT
DEFININGIC ITS GAME THAT THERE
SHOULD BE THIS LINGERING
INFESTATION OF REALLY CORRUPT
PEOPLE WHO ARE STILL TRYING TO
DISMANTLE THE WISHES OF THE
PEOPLE, THE MANDATE THAT HAS
BEEN GIVEN TO BARACK OBAMA AND I
DON'T KNOW WHAT MORE THEY WANT.
THE ONLY THING LEFT FOR BARACK
OBAMA TO DO IS TO ORGANIZE A
THIRD WORLD DICTATOR TO PUT ALL
THESE GUYS IN JAIL FOR VIOLATING
THE AMERICAN DESIRE.
>> YEAH.
THROW THEM IN JAIL.
THAT'S HIS SOLUTION.
PRESIDENT OBAMA, ACT LIKE A
DICTATOR.
JOINING MEOR NOW WITH REACTION,
THE CO HOST OF THE FIVE, KILL
BERKIMBERLY GUILFOYLE.
HE SAID THAT ABOUT NELSON
MANDELA.
HE SAID WE SALUTE YOU AND WANT
TO SEE YOU Y AND YOUR FELLOW
POLITICAL PRISONERS FREED.
REACTION?
>> WELL, I THINK THAT HARRY
BELAFONTE WAS JUST SAYING WHAT
HE SAID IN JEST.
YOU KNOWFO HE WAS JOKING.
>> Sean: IN JEST?
>> HE WAS JOKING AROUND.
HE DIDN'T MEAN IT.
>> Sean: THERE'S A WHOLE LIST OF
THINGS HE SAID IN JEST.
>> DO YOU HAVE THE LIST OF HIM
CRITICIZING PRESIDENT OBAMA
WHICH HE DID AND THE RIGHT WING
LOVED THAT.
>> Sean: HE COMPARED THEEA
ROSENBERG'S TO POLITICAL
PRISONERS AND COMPARED THE BUSH
ADMINISTRATION AND THE DHS SO
THE GESTAPO.
>> AND HE CRITICIZED OBAMA, TOO.
AND JAY-Z AND BEYONCE.
>> Sean: HE SUPPORTS A COP
KILLER.
I MEAN, HOW MORE EXTREME CAN YOU
GET?
>> WELL, I THINK HE --
>
>> Sean: YOU DON'T SEEM FAZED AT
ALL.
>> HE WAS SAYING IT IN JEST.
HE DID NOT REALLY MEAN THAT.
>> Sean: EVERY DUMB THING HE
SAYS NOW IS IN JEST?
I SAY DUMB THINGS, PEOPLE START
CAMPAIGNS TO SILENCE ME.
>> THEY DO BECAUSE THEY KNOW
YOU'RE NOT KIDDING.
HE'S PREPARING FOR A ROLE.
THIS IS A SCRIPT THAT'S
UNBELIEVABLE, THE STUFF HE HAD
TO SAY.
WHEN HE WAS CREATING PRESIDENT
OBAMA, IT'S BECAUSE HE WASN'T
CHAVEZ ENOUGH.
HE DIDN'T GO FAR ENOUGH IN HIS
SOCIALIST AGENDA.
IT WASN'T GOOD ENOUGH.
OBAMA'S AGENDA WASN'T LIBERAL
ENOUGH.
HE'S QUITE SERIOUS ABOUT WHAT
HE'S SAYING.
THIS IS THE DIRECTION HE
BELIEVESS  THE COUNTRY SHOULD BE
GOING IN.
HE SEEMS TO DISREGARD THE
PLEURALTY OF THE COUNTRY THAT,
IN FACT, DIDN'T WANT PRESIDENT
OBAMA TO BE REELECTED AND
OUTRIGHT REJECTED HIS LIBERAL
AGENDA.
THAT SEEMS TO HAVE FALLEN UPON
DEAF AREAS OR AT LEAST HARRY
BELAFONTE IS NOT LISTENING.
>> Sean: DO YOU LIKE RG-III HAS
MUCH AS I DO?
I MEAN, I'M SERIOUS, AND I'M A
JETS FAN.
AREIT YOU AS IMPRESSED WITH HIMS
I AM AS A PERSON, AS AN
INDIVIDUAL?
>>IV RIGHT.
>> Sean: ISN'T HE AMAZING?
HE WAS ONCE ASKED ABOUT WHO HE
FEARS.
HE SAID GOD.
I FEAR GOD.
>> THAT'S A GOOD ANSWER.
>> Sean: HE'S A GOOD PERSON,
GOOD HEART, GOOD SOUL.
HERE'S WHATHA ESPN, THIS ANALYST
HAD TO SAY ABOUT HIM, ROB
PARKER.
LISTEN TOB THIS.
>> MY QUESTION WHICH IS JUST A
STRAIGHT HONEST QUESTION.
>> YES, SIR.
>> WAS HE A CORN BALL BROTHER.
>> WHAT DOESTH THAT MEAN?
>> HE'S NOT REALLY, OKAY.
HE DOES THE THING BUT HE'S NOT
REALLY DOWN WITH THE CAUSE.
HE'S NOT ONE OF US.
HE'S KIND OF BLACK.
HE'S NOT REALLY LIKE THE GUY YOU
REALLY WANT TO HANG OUT WITH
BECAUSE HE'S OFF TO SOMETHING.
>> WHY IS THAT YOUR QUESTION?
>> WELL, BECAUSE THAT'S JUST HOS
I WANT TO FIND OUT ABOUT HIM.
I DON'T KNOW BECAUSE A I KEEP
HEARING THESE THINGS.
WE ALL KNOW HE HAS A WHITE
FIANCE.
THERE'S A ALL THIS TALK ABOUT HS
A REPUBLICAN WHICH THERE'S NO
INFORMATION AT ALL.
I'M JUST TRYING TO DIG DEEPER
INTO WHY HE HAS AN ISSUE.
>> Sean: HE DOESN'T HAVE THE
ISSUE.
>> THAT'S CRAZY.
IT'S AWFUL.
IT'S A HATE-FILLED SPEECH.
THOSE ARE RACIST COMMENTS.
WHY IS HE SAYING THAT.
HE HAS A WHITE FIANCE.
HE'S A REPUBLICAN SO HE WANTS TO
DISAVOW AND SAY HE'S NOT
AFRICAN-AMERICAN?
IT'S VERY STRANGE BEHAVIOR AND
REALLY RUDE.
>> Sean: REACTION?
>> I'M IN SHOCK FOR TWO REASONS.
NUMBER ONE, I THINK HIS COMMENTS
WERE TERRIBLE TO CRITICIZE A MAN
FOR HAVING A WHITE FIANCE.
AWFUL.
TERRIBLE.
I'M IN SHOCK FOR ANOTHER REASON.
I AGREE WITH YOU, SEAN.
IT'S A BREAKING NEWS ALERT.
HIS COMMENTS WERE WAY OUT OF
LINE.
IT HAS NOTHING TO DO WITH
SPORTS.
>> Sean: IF SOMEBODY HAS AN
HONEST DISAGREEMENT WITH SUSAN
RICE BECAUSE SHE KNEW -- WE KNEW
THAT THISW WAS NOT RELATED TO
YouTUBE VIDEO.
SHE SAID IT FIVE TIMES.
IF YOU'RE CRITICAL, IT'S A WAR
ON WOMEN AND YOU'RE RACIST.
THIS IS AN ONGOING FALSE
NARRATIVE ABOUT REPUBLICANS AND
I'M SICK OF IT.
I DON'T KNOW CONSERVATIVES THAT
ARE RACIST.
THEY'RE NOT FRIENDS OF OUR AND
THEY'RE NOT IN THE REPUBLICAN
PARTY, AND IF THEY ARE, I WANT
THEM OUT.
THIS NARRATIVE PUSHED BY
LIBERALS IN THE MEDIA, I'M FED
UP AND SICK AND TIRED OF IT.
NBC IS THE WORST.
THEY PLAY THE RACE CARD EVERY
SINGLE DAY.
>> THIS IS WHEREW YOU LOSE ME.
I WAS WITH YOU.
I WAS,  WITH YOU SEAN, BUT NO.
HERE'S MY THING.
I DON'T THINK IT'S A NARRATIVE
BEING PUSHED.
THED. REALITY IS WHAT JOHN
McCAIN SAID ABOUT SUSAN RICE.
LET'S REMEMBER THE CONTEXT.
SUSAN RICE HAD NO ROLE OR
RESPONSIBILITY OVER THAT
EMBASSY.
>> Sean: SHE KNEW WITHIN HOURS.
>> SHE HAD NO ROLE OR
RESPONSIBILITY.
WHYSPWH IS JOHN McCAIN MORE UPST
WITH HER THAN THE PERSON WHO HAD
RESPONSIBILITY.
>> Sean: JOHN IS MORTHE UPSET WH
THE PRESIDENT.
WE'VE GOTTA GO.
YOU'RE YELLING IN MY EAR.
I HATE WHENY I GET YELLED AT.
THANKS, GUYS.
>>> COMING UP NEXT, WE'RE BACK
WITH THIS WEEK'S WORST EXAMPLES
OF LIB RA MEDI LIBERAL MEDIA.
WE NEED TO HELP THIS MAN, JON
HAMMAR, HE'S BEING HELD IN
MAXIMUM CAN PRISON.
-- MEXICAN PRISON.
HE'S BEING DETAINED.
HE WENT IN AND TRIED TO REGISTER
AN ANTIQUE RIFLE IN MEXICO.
WHERE IS THE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION TO GET THIS GUY
FREE FOR CHRISTMAS?
STRAIGHT AHEAD.
CHRISTMAS?!
[ Female Announcer ]
IF YOU CARE FOR SEONE WITH
MILD TO MODERATE ALZHEIMER'S,
YOU'LL ALSO CARE ABOUT
OUR NEW OFFER.
YOU GET ACCESS TO NURSES WHO
CAN HELP WITH YOUR QUESONS.
AND YOUR LOVED ONE CAN GE
EXELON PATCH FREE FOR 30 DAYS.
IF THE DOCTOR FEELS
IT'S RIGHT FOR THEM.
IT CANNOCHANGE
HOW THE DIASE PROGRESSES.
HOSPITALIZATION
AND RARELY ATH
HAVE BEEN REPORTED IN PATIENTS
WHO WORE MORE THAN ONE PATCH
AT A TIME.
THE MOST COMMON SIDE EFFECTS
OF EXELON PATCH
ARE NAUSEA, VOMITING,
AND DIARRHEA.
THE LIKELIHOOD AND SEVERITY
OF THESE SIDE EFFECTS
MAY INCREASE
AS THE DOSE INCREASES.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
LOSS OF APPETITE OR WEIGHT.
PATIENTS WHO WEIGH
LESS THAN 110 POUNDS
MAY EXPERIENCE
MORE SIDE EFFECTS.
PEOPLE AT RISK
FOR STOMACH ULCERS
WHO TAKE CERTAIN
OTHER MEDICINES
SHOULD TALK TO THEIR DOCTOR
BECAUSE SERIOUS
STOMACH PROBLEMS
SUCH AS BLEEDING MAY WORSEN.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
SLOW HEART RATE.
THIRTY DAYS OF EXELON PATCH
FREE FOR YOUR LOVED ONE.
ACCESS TO TRAINED NURSES
FOR YOU.
CALL 1-855-999-1399
OR VISIT EXELONPATCHOFFER2.COM.
[ engine revs ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THE MERCEDES-BENZ WINTER EVENT
IS BACK,
WITH THE PERFECT VEHICLE
THAT'S JUST RIGHT FOR YOU,
NO MATTER WHICH LIST YOU'RE ON.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
C250 FOR $349 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
IMPACT WOOL EXPORTS
FROM NEW ZEALAND,
TEXTILE PRODUCTION IN SPAIN,
AND THE USE OF MEDICAL
TECHNOLOGY IN THE U.S.?
AT T. ROWE PRICE,
WE UNDERSTAND THE CONNECTIONS
OF A COMPLEX, GLOBAL ECONOMY.
IT'S JUST ONE REASON
OVER 75% OF OUR MUTUAL FUNDS
BEAT THEIR 10-YEAR
LIPPER AVERAGE.
T. RO PRICE.
INVEST WITH CONFIDENCE.
REQUEST A PROSPECTUS
OR SUMMARY PROSPECTUS
WITH INVESTMENT INFORMATION,
RISKS, FEES AND EXPENSES
TO READ AND CONSIDER CAREFULLY
BEFORE INVESTING.
BY SHOWING YOU
THE APARTMENT BUILDING
>> I THOUGHT I WOULD START YOU
THE
RED CROSS PUT US IN A HOTEL
SO WE WERE ABLE
TO STAY TOGETHER.
WE'RE STRONG
AND IF WE OVERCAME THAT
OR IF WE CAN OVERCOME THAT...
WE CAN OVERCOME ANYTHING.
[ SNIFFLES ]
♪
>> Sean: WELCOME BACK TO
HANNITY.
TIME FOR MEDIA MASH, OUR WEEKLY
ROUND UP OF ALL THE WAYS THE
MAIN EXTREME MEDIA TRIES TO PUT
THEIR LIBERAL SPIN ON THEIR
NEWS.
WHEN IT CAMENE TO COVERING THE
PASSAGE OF THE RIGHT TO WORK
LEGISLATION IN MICHIGAN, THEY
COULDN'T HIDE THEIR BIAS.
HERE TO EXPLAIN IT, BROTHER
BOZELL.
HOW ARE. YOU, SIR.
>> BROTHER HANNITY, HOW ARE YOU
DOING?
>> Sean: I'M DOING GOOD.
WE HAVE ALL THIS UNFOLD.
WE HAVE STEVE CROWDER PUNCHED,
NOT PROVOKING ANYBODY.
WEHI HAVE ALL THE VIOLENCE.
NONE OF THE NETWORKS COVERED IT.
THERE'S A STORY.
I INTERVIEWED A GUY THAT WAS
THERE, W 16 YEARS, HAS A HOT DOG
STAND IN LANSING WHO WAS HIRED
BY AMERICANS FOR PROSPERITY.
I PLAYED A TAPE EARLIER WHERE HE
DISCUSSES HOW HE WAS CALLED THE
N WORD AND ALL THESE HORRIBLE
NAMES, AND HE ALSO DESCRIBED HOW
THEY RUINED HIS EQUIPMENT.
LISTEN TO THIS.
>> WHAT HAPPENED?
WALK US THROUGH WHAT HAPPENED
THE OTHER DAY WHEN THEY
COLLAPSED THAT TENT.
>> WELL, I SET UP AROUND 10:00
A.M., AND
EVERYTHING WAS GOING
GOOD.
10:30 I STARTED SERVING HOT
DOGS, AND I WOULD SAY ABOUT
QUARTER TO 12 IS WHEN TWO GUYS,
ONE HAD LIKE A HALLOWEEN DEVIL'S
MASK ON.
THE OTHER HAD A SKI MASK ON.
I THOUGHT IT WAS JUST A PRANK,
EVERYBODY WAS HAVINGWA FUN.
ANY WAY, SO I GAVE THE MAN HOOT
DOG.
EVERYBODY HAD TO HAVE A TICKET,
SO THEY HAD TICKETS.
I GAVE THEM A HOT DOG, AND WHEN
THEY GOT THROUGH EATING THE HOT
DOGS, THEY TURNED OVER THE
COFFEE URN.
BY THAT TIME THE PROTESTERS WERE
TEARING THE TENT DOWN, AND SO
THE GROUNDS KEEPER OF THE
CAPITAL SAID CLINT, YOU HAVE TO
GET OUT OF HERE.
THEY'RE TEARING THE TENT DOWN.
>> Sean: THEN THEY CALLED HIM
THE N WORD RIGLEHT TO HIS FACE.
REACTION.
WHY DIDN'T THE MEDIA COVER THAT?
>>TI WELL, I THINK YOUR VIEWERS
NEED TO THINK ABOUT TWO THINGS.
ONE IS REMEMBER THE DOZENS, THE
HUNDREDS OF STORIES THAT WE'VE
WATCHEDTH SINCE 2009 ABOUT THE
MENACING NATURE OF THE TEA
PARTY, AND A ACCUSATIONS
MADE ABOUT THE TEA PARTY.
NEVER MIND THAT THERE WAS NO
EVIDENCE EVER TO BACK UP THE N
WORD WITH THE TEA PARTY OR GABI
GIFFORDS OR SO MANY OF THE
SHOOTING IN COLORADO, ALL
THESE THINGS ATTRIBUTED TO THE
AT A PARTY.
NONE OF IT WAS TRUE.
THIS MEDIAS WAS OBSESSIVE ABOUT
THE NEED FOR CIVILITY IN THE
AMERICAN PUBLIC CONVERSATION.
OKAY.
SO NOW THE TABLES ARE TURNED,
AND NOW YOU'VE GOT OUTRIGHT
VIOLENCE Y BEING PERPETRATORD.
>> Sean: AND RACISM.
>> BUT SEAN, WHAT'S KEY HERE IS
THAT REPORTERS WERE THERE.
THAT SCENE IS CRAWLING WITH
JOURNALISTS.
THEY'RE ALL THERE.
THEY'RE SEEING IT WITH THEIR OWN
EYES.
THEY MISSED THE
STORY.
IT'S NOT LIKE THEY DIDN'T HAVE
THE FOOTAGE.
IT'S NOT LIKE NOBODY TOLD THEM
ABOUT IT.
THEY WERE THERE, THEY SAW IT,
AND STILL THEY WITH HELD IT FROM
THE PUBLIC.
>> Sean: ALL RIGHT.
SO THERE WAS NO REFERENCE IN THE
MAIN STREAM MEDIA THIS WEEK TO
THE VIOLENCE THAT OCCURRED.
YOU RIGHTLY POINT OUT THAT THEY
WERE THERE, SO WE DECIDED TO GO
BACK AND WE DID A LITTLE SEARCH.
NOW, YOU HAVE A HUNDRED PERCENT
PEACEFUL MOVEMENT KNOWN AS THE
TEA PARTY.
THEY SEARCHED HIGH AND LOW.
THEY COULDN'T FIND RACISM OR
VIOLENCE, BUT THAT'S NOT HOW
THEY PORTRAYED IT.
THE SAME PEOPLE THAT IGNORED
THIS MAN'S STORY AND THE
VIOLENCE.
LISTEN TO THIS.
>> A T YEAR-LONG DEBATE THAT HAS
BEEN MEAN FROMND THE START TURND
EVEN NASTIER YESTERDAY.
DEMONSTRATORS PROTESTING THE
BILLST POURED INTO THE HALLS OF
CONGRESS SHOUTING KILL THE BILL
AND MADE IN THE USSR.
>> OPPONENTS OF THE BILL HAVE
BEEN OUT TODAY.
SOME OF THEM PULLED OUT ALL THE
STOPS.
PROTESTERS ROAMING WASHINGTON
TON, SOME OF THEM INCREASINGLY
EMOTIONAL, YELLING SLURS AND
EPITHETS.
>> WHEN HAMAS OR HEZBOLLAH DOES
IT, IT'S CALLED TERRORISM.
WHY SHOULD THE ASTRO TURF GROUPS
ORGANIZING ON BEHALF OF THE
HEALTH CARE MOVEMENT BE VIEWED
DIFFERENTLY.
THEY'RE BEING CARRIE COMPARED TR
AND THE HOLOCAUST.
>> Sean: TERRORISTS, SLURS,
MEAN, EPITHETS, AND THEY COULD
NOT PRODUCE IT.
THERES  WAS A $100,000 REWARD.
>> IT'S TIME FOR THE TEA PARTY
TOIG CONSIDER DEMONSTRATIONS IN
FRONT OF NBC, ABC, THE "NEW YORK
TIMES", NEVER MIND THE MALL.
GO TO THESE NETWORKS.
IT'S TIME FOR THERE TO BE A
NATIONAL OUTRAGE AGAINST WHAT
THEY'RE DOING.
>> Sean: BRENT BOZELL, THANKS
FOR BEING WITH US.
>>>CO WHEN WE COME BACK, THERE'A
FAMILY THATHA NEEDS YOUR HELP.
THIS MARINE, JON HAMMAR, IS
BEING HELD RIGHT NOW AND HAS
BEEN SINCE AUGUST IN A MEXICAN
PRISON.
HE TRIED TO LEGALLY REGISTER AN
ANTIQUE RIFLEIF IN MEXICO.
HE WAS ENROUTE TO COSTA RICA.
HE HAS BEEN LOCKED UP FOR FOUR
MONTHS AND MEXICAN AUTHORITIES
REFUSE TO RELEASE HIM.
HIS PARENTS JOIN ME NEXT, AND
YOU CAN HELP THEM.
ETHING
ALONG THE WAY.
THIS IS THE AGE OF KNOWING
WHAT YOU'RE MADE OF.
SO, WHY LET
ERECTILE DYSFUNCTION
GET IN YOUR WAY?
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT VIAGRA.
20 MILLION MEN ALREADY HAVE.
ASK IF YOUR HEART
IS HEALTHY ENOUGH FOR SEX.
DO NOT TAKE VIAGRA IF YOU TAKE
NITRATES FOR CHEST PAIN;
IT MAY CAUSE AN UNSAFE DROP
IN BLOOD PRESSURE.
SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE
HEADACHE, FLUSHING,
UPSET STOMACH,
AND ABNORMAL VISION.
TO AVOID LONG-TERM INJURY,
SEEK IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
FOR AN ERECTION
LASTING MORE THAN FOUR HOURS.
STOP TAKING VIAGRA
AND CALL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU EXPERIENCE
A SUDDEN DECREASE OR LOSS
IN VISION OR HEARING.
THIS IS THE AGE
OF TAKING ACTION.
VIAGRA.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR.
SEE IF AMERICA'S
MOST PRESCRIBED ED TREATMENT
IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
>>
>> Sean: A ROAD TRIP WITH
FRIENDS TURNED INTO A NIGHTMARE
FOR AD OR BRAVE MARINE THAT BEHY
SERVED -- BRAVELY SERVED OUR
COUNTRIES IN MISSIONS IN
AFGHANISTAN AND IRAQ.
HE WAS ENROUTE TO COSTA RICA.
HE WAS ARRESTED FOR CARING THIS
ANTIQUE SHOTGUN THAT WAS OWNED
BY HIS GRANDFATHER.
NOW, ACCORDING TO REPORTS, JON
HAMMAR REGISTERED THE GUNS WITH
U.S. CUSTOMS AND BORDER
PROTECTION OFFICIALS AND WAS
TOLD WHEN THEY CROSSES THE
BORDER, HE SHOULD DO THE SAME
THING IN MEXICO.
IT TURNED OUT NOT TO BE THE
CASE.
ON AUGUST THE 20th WHEN HAMMAR
TRIED TO REGISTER THE GUN
LEGALLY WHEN HE CROSSED THE
BORDER, HE WAS ARRESTED AND
CHARGED WITH CARRYING A DEADLY
WEAPON AND THROWN IN JAIL.
HERE IT IS FOUR MONTHS LATER AND
JON IS SITTING  IN A NOTORIOUSLY
DANGEROUS MEXICAN PRISON.
UP UNTIL TWO DAYS AGO HE HAS
BEEN CHAINED TO A BED.
HIS PARENTS HAVE GOTTEN PHONE
CALLS IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT
THREATENING TO KILL HIS SON
UNLESS THEY WIRE MONEY THROUGH
WESTERN UNION.
JOINING US ARE HIS PAIRNTSZ.
THANK YOU, OLIVIA AND JON FOR
BEING HERE.
>> THANKS FOR HAVING US.
>> Sean: HE SERVED IN IRAQ AND
AFGHANISTAN, HAS PTSD.
HE TRIETD TO GET SOME HELP.
HE'S GOING ON VACATION WITH HIS
FRIENDS.
HE GETS TO THE AMERICAN BORDER
AND TELLS THEM HE HAS THIS GUN
IN HIS RV, RIGHT, OLIVIA?
>> RIGHT.
HE DISCLOSED IT WITH A U.S.
CUSTOMS GUIDE.
THEY TOOK PICTURES.
THEY WEIGHED IT.
THEY GAVE HIM SOME PAPERS TO
FILL OUT SO THAT HE COULD THEN
TAKE THAT REGISTRATION PAPER TO
THE MEXICAN CUSTOMS AS HE
CROSSED.
>> Sean: SO HE'S SUPPOSED TO
CROSS THE BORDER AND HAND IT TO
OFFICIALS AS HE WAS TOLD TO DO.
IS THAT WHAT HAPPENED?
>> RIGHT.
>> Sean: OKAY.
WHAT HAPPENS NEXT?
>> HE WAS IMMEDIATELY ARRESTED.
HE DECLARED THE WEAPON AND WAS
IMMEDIATELY ARRESTED.
>> Sean: SO HE'S DECLARING THE
WEAPON.
NOT LIKEEA THESE TRYIN HE'S TRYG
THIS TH
ING IN MEXICO.
THEY ARREST HIM BACK IN AUGUST.
WHAT HAPPENED SINCE THEN, AND
WHAT IS THE STATUS AND HOW CAN
WE HELP GET YOUR SON HOME BY
CHRISTMAS?
>> AFTER THEY ARRESTED HIM, WE
GET A CALL FROM THE U.S.
CONSULATE THAT HE HAD BEEN
ARRESTED, AND THEN A COUPLE DAYS
AFTER THAT WEEN GET A CALL FROM
SOMEONE WHO SAID THIS IS NOT
ABOUT THE POLICE.
WE HAVE YOUR SON.
IF YOU DON'T WIRE $1800 TO A
WESTERN UNION ACCOUNT, WE'RE
GOING TO KILLCC HIM, AND HERE HE
IS.
LISTEN TO HIM.
TALK TO HIM.
AND SO WE TALKED TO HIM, AND WE
SAID WELL, I'M NOT SURE ABOUT
WESTERN UNION.
HE SAID WE'LL CALL YOU BACK WITH
AN ACCOUNT NUMBER.
>> Sean: SO THAT CORRUPTION HAD
TO BE HAPPENING WITHIN THE
MEXICAN JAIL.
>> THAT WAS INSIDE -- IT WAS
INSIDE THE PRISON, YES, BECAUSE
THEN WE FIND OUT -- THEN WE
CALLEDLE THE CONSULATE AND TOLD
THEM WHAT WAS GOING ON.
AS WE'RE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
THIS WESTERN UNION ACCOUNT
NUMBER, THEY SAID WELL, WE'RE ON
IT.
WE'RE GOING TO CALL THE PRISON
OFFICIALS AND GET TO THE BOTTOM
OF IT AND HAVE HIM ISOLATED.
>> Sean: OLIVIA, I KNOW BARACK
OBAMA DOESN'T REALLY LISTEN TO
ME, BUT THIS MIGHT BE AN
OPPORTUNITY FOR HIM TO STEP UP.
TELL THE MEXICAN GOVERNMENT
RELEASE THIS KID, AN AMERICAN
HERO WHO HAS BEEN SUFFERING IN
THIS PRISON SINCE AUGUST.
WHAT'S THE STATUS AND HOW CAN
PEOPLE HELP YOU?
>> YOU KNOW, WE'RE JUST ASKING
FOR EVERYONE T AO TALK TO THEIR
LAWMAKERS.
I MEAN, I WOULD JUST MAKE A
PERSONAL PLEA TO THE PRESIDENT
TO CONTACT, YOU KNOW, THIS NEW
INCOMING PRESIDENT NIETO OF
MEXICO AND JUST ASK HIM TO
RESOLVE THIS CASE AND SEND HIM
HOME.
THIS HAS GONE ON TOO LONG.
IT'S A RIDICULOUS CASE.
I THINK THEY KNOW IT'S A
RIDICULOUS CASE BECAUSE IT WAS
AN ACCIDENT.
IT'S A CASE THAT THE THEIR OWN
MILITARY HAS SENT LETTERS TO THE
JUDGES AND THE PROSECUTORS
SAYING THIS GUN IS NOT ON THE
RESTRICTED LIST THAT IS TRYING
TO RESTRICT, YOU KNOW, ASSAULT
RIFLES, ESSENTIALLY.
THERE SAYING THIS ISN'T ANYTHING
LIKEHI THIS, AND THE PROSECUTORS
AND THE JUDGES HAVE REFUSED TO
CONSIDER