ARE MISSING THAT WILL MAKE IT
MORE DIFFICULT --
>> YES, THERE ARE PIECES MISSING
THAT WE HAVEN'T HAD A CHANCE TO
FINISH YET.
THE FORENSIC PART IS AN
IMPORTANT PART.
THAT'S BEING WORKED ON BUT IT'S
NOT DONE YET.
THE WITNESSES NEED TO BE
INTERVIEWED.
THERE IS AN IMMENSE NUMBER OF
WITNESSES THAT NEED TO BE
INTERVIEWED.
THAT'S NOT COMPLETED.
THERE ARE WEEKS OF WORK WE HAVE
LEFT IN ORDER TO COMPLETE THIS.
I WOULD LIKE TO SAY THAT WE
WILL -- WE WILL COME BACK IN A
COUPLE OF HOURS.
I APOLOGIZE FOR HAVING YOU OUT
HERE IN THE INCLEMENT WEATHER.
WE ARE ALSO.
BUT I WANT TO GET THE
INFORMATION FROM THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER'S OFFICE FOR AND YOU
CONFIRM THAT.
I WANT TO SEE IF I CAN GET MORE
DETAIL RELATIVE TO THE
PRESIDENTIAL VISIT AND THE
LOGISTICS OF THAT THIS AFTERNOON
AND IF THERE ARE ANY UPDATES
FROM THE MAJOR CRIME COMMANDERS
OF THE DEPARTMENT, I WILL BRING
THAT TO YOU.
OKAY?
>> Reporter: WHAT FEDERAL
CRIME SCENE PROGRAM IS WORKING?
>> FEDERAL AUTHORITIES.
I VALID TO CONSULT WITH THE U.S.
ATTORNEY ON THAT.
I SIMPLY DO NOT.
WE WILL BE BACK IN A COUPLE OF
HOURS.
FOLK, PLEASE STAY DRY.
>> ERIC: THAT'S LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE, BEING VERY SPECIFIC AND
CAREFUL, AS YOU HEARD, NOT
COMMENTING ON THE REPORTS THAT
NANCY LANZA WILL TAKE HER SON TO
THE SHOOTING RANGE OR USE THE
GUNS TO GO TO THE SHOOTING RANGE
AND SAYING THERE IS SICK STUFF
ON THE INTERNET.
CLAIMING TO BE THE LANZAS
THEMSELVES AND THAT'S A FEDERAL
CRIME.
AFTER THIS HORRIFIC TRAGEDY THAT
HAS THE PRAYERS AND THE
COMPASSION OF THE NATION.
>> JAMIE: A LOT OF PRAYERS FOR
ALL THE VICTIMS.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
WE'LL CONTINUE TO UPDATE YOU.
THE PRESIDENT VISITING TONIGHT,
BRET BAIER, 6:00 P.M., NOW
WASHINGTON WILL TAKE OVER.
>> ERIC: HAVE A GOOD DAY,
EVERYBODY.
>> JAMIE: A NATION MOURNS THE
LIVES OF THE TRAGEDY FROM SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY.
POLICE SAY THEY HAVE UNCOVERED
EVIDENCE IN THE CASE AND THEY
ARE TRACING ALL THE WEAPON, ALL
THE WAY BACKTO THE WORK BENCHES
WHERE THEY WERE MADE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA PREPARING TO FLY
TO NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, TO ACT
OZ OUR COUNTRY'S CONSOLER IN
CHIEF.
AS AUTHORITIES RELEASE THE NAMES
OF THE SCHOOL STAFF AND CHILDREN
WHO WERE KILLED, WE LEARN, NOT
ONLY THE TERRIBLE DETAILS ABOUT
THEIR LAST MOMES AND THE
TOUCHING STORIES OF THE LIVES
BEHIND THE NAMES.
I'M BREAM -- I'M SHANNON BREAM
WITH AMERICA'S NEWS HEADQUARTERS
LIVE FROM THE NATION'S CAPITOL,
STARTING NOW.
POLICE ARE WORKING TO DRAW A
MORE COMPLETE PICTURE OF THE MAN
WHO CAME TO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY AND KILLED CHILDREN.
PETER DOOCY HAS THE LATEST.
>> Reporter: WITH THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE PRESS
CONFERENCE THAT JUST WRAPPED,
THE MOST COMPELLING PART,
PERHAPS, WAS WHEN THE LIEUTENANT
BASICALLY WARNED PEOPLE WHO HAVE
BEEN SOMEHOW -- WE DON'T KNOW
SPECIFICALLY -- BUT USING SOCIAL
MEDIA TO POSE AS THE SHOOTER AND
TO OFFER SOME KIND OF
MISINFORMATION.
AND THE CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
WARNED WHOEVER HAS BEEN USING
THE SOCIAL MEDIA TO PERPETRATE
MISINFORMATION, THAT THEY WILL
BE PROSECUTED FOR CRIMES IN THE
STATE OF CONNECTICUT AND FOR
FEDERAL CRIMES.
AGAIN, WE DON'T KNOW
SPECIFICALLY WHAT HE WAS
REFERRING TO, BUT WE DO PLAN TO
LOOK INTO IT.
THIS JUST HAPPENED.
AND HE SAID THAT THE CRIME SCENE
OUTSIDE THE SCHOOL HAS BEEN
PROCESSED AND THE CARS THAT WERE
PART OF THIS, THE VEHICLES HAVE
ALL STARTED TO BE RETURNED TO
THEIR OWNERS AND THE INSIDE OF
THE CRIME SCENE IS BEING WORKED
ON BY AUTHORITIES AND THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE ALSO
SAID THAT THEY WILL NOT BE
RELEASING A TIMELINE ABOUT THE
EVENTS THAT OCCURRED DURING ADAM
LANZA'S RAMPAGE.
BUT SOMETHING INTERESTING THAT
WE HEARD THIS MORNING FROM THE
LIEUTENANT GOVERNOR MALLOY WAS
THAT BASED ON HIS UNDERSTANDING
OF THE RECONSTRUCTION OF THE
CRIME SCENE INSIDE ONE OF THE
CLASSROOM, THE GUNMAN DECIDED TO
TAKE HIS OWN LIFE AS SOON AS HE
HEARD THAT AUTHORITIES, WHO WERE
ALSO ARMED, WERE GETTING CLOSE.
LISTEN TO THIS.
>> WE SURMISE THAT IT WAS DURING
THE SECOND CLASSROOM EPISODE AND
HE HEARD THE RESPONDERS COMING
AND HE DECIDED TO TAKE HIS OWN
LIFE.
>> Reporter: AGAIN, RIGHT NOW,
THERE IS NO INFORMATION,
OFFICIALLY, OR UNOFFICIALLY
ABOUT WHAT A MOTIVE MIGHT HAVE
BEEN.
THE STATE POLICE WERE ASKED IF
THEY WERE CONFIDENT THAT WE WILL
EVER KNOW WHAT THE MOTIVE WAS.
HE SAID THEY ARE GOING TO ANSWER
EVERY POSSIBLE QUESTION IN THIS
CASE, AS BEST AS IS HUMANLY
POSSIBLE.
BUT MORE INFORMATION IS COMING
FROM ONE OF THE PARENTS, A
SIX-YEAR-OLD FIRST GRADER WHO
SAW HIS TEACHER, THE 27-YEAR-OLD
VICTORIA SOTO, GOT SHOT AND HE
RAN AWAY AND HE IS TELLING MORE
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED, EVERY
SINGLE DAY.
IT'S VERY COMPELLING.
LISTEN TO THIS.
>> THE CHILDREN ACTED ON
INSTINCT AND WHAT THEY WERE
TAUGHT, WHICH WAS TO RUN.
AND THEY D. THEY JUST RAN UP TO
THE MAIN ROAD, 100 YARDS AWAY.
MY SON AND SEVERAL OF HIS OTHER
STUDENTS WERE EXTREMELY BRAVE IN
WHAT THEY DID AND ACTED WITH
COURAGE THAT I DON'T KNOW THAT I
HAVE.
>> Reporter: OBVIOUSLY, RIGHT
NOW, THE SHATTERED COMMUNITY IS
TRYING TO PUT THE PIECES BACK
TOGETHER, SO MANY PEOPLE WERE
LOST AND THE AUTHORITIES WERE
ASKED TODAY, IF THEY THINK THOSE
STUDENTS WHO WERE INSIDE THE
SCHOOL ARE EVER GOING TO BE ABLE
TO GO BACK TO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY AND THE LOCAL POLICE
SAY THEY THINK IT WILL BE VERY
DIFFICULT.
BUT IT'S GOING TO BE IMPORTANT
TO KEEP THE STUDENTS TOGETHER.
SO THEY ARE WORKING ON SOME KIND
OF A CONTINGENCY PLAN THAT CAN
KEEP THE STUDENTS TOGETHER AND
PERHAPS ALLOW THEM NOT TO EVER
GO BACK TO THE PLACE WHERE THEY
EXPERIENCED SUCH A NIGHTMARE ON
FRIDAY.
>> THANK YOU.
ROBBIE PARKER, THE DAD OF
SIX-YEAR-OLD EMILIE, ONE OF THE
FIRST PARENTS TO SPEAK OUT ABOUT
THE SHOOTING.
HE DESCRIBES HIS DAUGHTER AS A
HAPPY LITTLE GIRL WHO LIKED TO
MAKE CARDS AND ALMOST ALWAYS
CARRIED COLORED PINSILS AND
MARKERS.
SHE LOVED HER LITTLE SISTERS AND
CHEERING UP HER SAD FRIENDS.
SHE DESCRIBED HIS LAST MOMENTS S
WITH HIS OLDEST DAUGHTER FRIDAY
MORNING.
>> MY DAUGHTER, EMILIE:  WOULD
BE ONE OF THE FIRST ONES TO BE
STANDING AND GIVING HER LOVE AND
SUPPORT TO ALL OF THOSE VICTIMS
BECAUSE THAT'S THE TYPE OF
PERSON THAT SHE IS.
NOT BECAUSE OF ANY PARENTING
THAT MY WIFE AND I COULD HAVE
DONE, BUT BECAUSE THOSE ARE THE
GIFTS THAT WERE GIVEN TO HER BY
HER HEAVENLY FATHER.
>> ALSO EXPRESSING SYMPATHY FOR
THE FAMILY OF THE SHOOTER.
HE SENT LOVE AND SUPPORT FROM
HIS FAMILY TO THEIRS.
THE NATION UNITED AFTER PEOPLE
IN HIS DISTRICT WERE HIT HARD BY
SUPER STORM SANDY AND NOW THE
NEIGHBORS ARE STRUGGLING WITH AN
UNTHINKABLE TRAGEDY.
CONGRESSMAN KING IS HERE NOW.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
>> THANK YOU, SHANNON.
>> YOUR THOUGHTS.
YOU HAVE HAD TO ASSIST A LOT OF
PEOPLE SUFFERING IN A DIFFERENT
WAY.
NOW SOMETHING NEW.
>> YEAH.
THIS IS SO INDESCRIBABLE.
ANY NATURAL DISASTER IS TERRIBLE
ENOUGH.
BUT TO HAVE THE RANDOM, VICIOUS
SHOOTING OF YOUNG CHILDREN LIKE
THIS, IT'S REALLY BEYOND BELIEF.
I CAN'T THINK OF ANY OTHER
INCIDENT LIKE THIS, TOUCHING THE
AMERICAN PSYCHE THE WAY THAT
THIS HAS.
IT'S CAUSED SUCH SORROW.
OUR HEARTS AND RARES GO OUT TO
THE FAMILIES OF THESE PEOPLE AND
TO THE YOUNG KID WHO IS
SURVIVED.
IM TRYING TO THINK, BACK IN
GRADE SCHOOL, THINGS ARE TOUGH
ENOUGH, TRYING TO GO ON AFTER
THE CHILD NEXT TO YOU OR YOUR
BEST FRIEND -- TO ME, IT'S
INDESCRIBABLE, AS A COUNTRY, WE
HAVE TO FIND A WITO CONFRONT
THIS.
I DON'T KNOW IF DUMBING DOWN IS
THE RIGHT EXPRESSION, BUT IT
SEEMS LIKE EVERY MASS MURDER IS
WORSE THAN THE ONE BEFORE.
WHEN WE THINK WE HAVE HIT THE
WORSE, LIKE COLORADO AND THE
MALL AND NOW THIS.
IT SEEMS AS IF THE COUNTRY, IN
SOME RESPECTS IS IN A REAL
DOWNWARD DECLINE.
>> WE DID SEE AND WE CONTINUE TO
SEE IN THE WAKE OF SUPER STORM
SANDY, A LOT OF GOOD SAMARITANS
AND PEOPLE REACHING OUT, EVEN
WHEN THEY ARE SUFFERING TO HELP
OTHERS.
DO YOU THINK WE WILL BE ABLE TO
SEE THAT HERE, AS SOON AS THE
VERY, VERY FRESH WOUNDS BEGIN TO
HEAL?
>> I THINK SO.
I THINK WE ARE SEEING IT
ALREADY.
NEIGHBORS, FRIEND, LAW
ENFORCEMENT, CLERKY, EVERYONE
COMING TOGETHER, MENTAL HEALTH
PROFESSIONALS, EVERYONE OFFERS
TO HELP.
WE SAW IT AFTER 9/11 AND AFTER
KATRINA, AFTER SANDY.
OBVIOUSLY, TO ME, WE ARE SEEING
IT ALREADY IN CONNECTICUT.
THAT REALLY IS THE HEART AND
SOUL OF AMERICA.
SO I DON'T WANT TO BE OVERLY
DOWN WHEN I SAY THAT THE COUNTRY
IS IN DECLINE.
THERE ARE ELEMENTS IN DECLINE,
BUT THE REAL HEART AND SOUL OF
AMERICA IS STRONGER THAN EVER.
>> OF COURSE, LIFE AND WORK
CONTINUES FOR MANY PEOPLE THIS
WEEK YOUR WORK ON THE HILL WITH
THE TWO BENGHAZI HEARINGS, ONE
IN THE HOUSE AND ONE IN THE
SENATE THIS WEEK.
BUT NEWS THAT SECRETARY CLINTON
IS ILL AND HAS BEEN INJURED WITH
A CONCUSSION AND WILL NOT
TESTIFY.
ARE YOU CONFIDENT THAT OTHERS
WHO WILL SHOW UP IN HER PLACE
WILL PROVIDE MUCH-NEEDED
ANSWERS.
>> I AM SURE THEY CAN PROVIDE
ANSWERS, BUT ULTIMATELY, I
BELIEVE THAT SECRETARY
CLINTONVILLE TO TESTIFY.
I HAVE A GREAT RESPECT FOR
SECRETARY CLINTON.
NO ONE WOULD KNOW MORE ABOUT
THIS THAN SHE WOULD.
NO ONE WOULD BE IN A POSITION,
REALLY TO ANSWER THE TOUGH
QUESTIONS OF SECRETARY CLINTON.
ONCE SHE HAS RECOVERED, I
BELIEVE IT IS IMPORTANT THAT SHE
TESTIFY.
I KNOW THAT THE CHAIRWOMAN OF
THE INTERNATIONAL AFFAIRS
COMMITTEE BELIEVES THAT
SECRETARY CLINTON IS AN
INDOZENSIBLE WITNESS.
WHAT HAPPENED IN BENGHAZI, THERE
ARE SO MANY UNANSWERED
QUESTIONS, IT APPEARS SO MANY
THINGS WENT WRONG AND TOO MANY
PEOPLE IN THE ADMINISTRATION
WERE TRYING TO PUT OUT A FALSE
STORY, WHICH ACCOUNTS, I
BELIEVE, FOR THE CONSTANT
CHANGING OF THE STORY, AS WE
HAVE GONE ON AND THE STILL
UNANSWERED QUESTION.
BUT ULTIMATELY, I BELIEVE THAT
SECRETARY CLINTON WILL TESTIFY
BECAUSE SHE REALLY IS IN
INDISPENSABLE.
>> AND THE FISCAL CLIFF
CONTINUES.
REPORTS THAT HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER WOULD BE OPEN TO RAISING
TAX RATE ON THOSE WHO MAKE A
MILLION DOLLARS OR MORE IN
EXAMPLE FOR MAJOR CUTS
ELSEWHERE.
IS THAT AN IDEA YOU CAN SUPPORT?
OR IS IT A NO-GO FOR YOU IF
THERE ARE ANY TAX INCREASES?
>> I HAVE GIVEN MY SUPPORT TO
JOHN BOEHNER.
WE'LL NEVER GET THE PERFECT
DEAL.
I AM CONFIDENT THAT JOHN WILL
GET THE BEST DEAL WE CAN, THE
PRESIDENT WON THE ELECTION, THE
DEMOCRATS TOOK THE SENATE, WE
TOOK THE HOUSE.
THERE IS BARG ANG GOINGOMP I
THINK IT'S WRONG FOR REPUBLICANS
TO BE SECOND-GUESSING WHAT JOHN
BOEHNER MIGHT BE DOING OR LAYING
OUT POSITIONS ABOUT WHAT THEY
CAN OR CANNOT SUPPORT.
VITOLD JOHN THAT BASED ON MY
KNOWLEDGE OF HIM AND HIS
COMMITMENT, I AM PREPARED TO
SUPPORT THE AGREEMENT THAT HE
ULTIMATELY NEGOTIATES, CONVINCED
THAT IT'S THE BEST WE GET UNDER
THE CIRCUMSTANCES.
>> CONGRESSMAN PETER KING, WE
THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME TODAY.
>> THANK YOU.
>> IN JUST A FEW HOUR, PRESIDENT
OBAMA WILL TRAVEL TO NEW TONG TO
MOURN THE VICTIMS AND CONSOLE
SURVIVORS AND MEET WITH
EMERGENCY WORKERS WHO RESPONDED
TO THE SHOOTING SCENE.
AT 7:00 EASTERN TIME, HE WILL
SPEAK AT AN INTERFAITH VIG NIL
NEWTOWN, HIGH SCHOOL.
WE WILL HAVE LIVE COVERAGE BY
BRET BAIER.
WHILE THE PRESIDENT PREPARES FOR
THE TRIP, LAWMAKERS ON CAPITOL
HILL ARE ROLLING OUT NEW
PROPOAFS IN THE WAKE OF THE
TRAGEDY, TWO SENATORS ARE
CALLING FOR A COMMISSION TO LOOK
INTO THE ISSUE OF MASS SHOOTINGS
HERE IN THE U.S., STEVE CENTANNI
HAS DETAILS.
>> FIRST, A HUGE OUTPOURING OF
SHOCK AND SYMPATHY HERE IN
WASHINGTON FOR THE FAMILIES OF
THOSE KILLED IN NEWTOWN.
AT THE SAME TIME, SOME IDEAS
AIMED AT PREVENTING THE SAME
THING FROM HAPPENING AGAIN,
OUTGOING SENATOR JOE BIEBERMAN,
INDEPENDENT FROM CONTACT
CONNECT, HAS THIS
RECOMMENDATION.
>> I THINK WE NEED A NATIONAL
COMMISSION ON MASS VIOLENCE.
NOT TO -- BE IN PLACE OF
ANYTHING ELSE -- THE PRESIDENT
OR CONGRESS OR STATE GOVERNMENTS
MIGHT WANT TO DO.
BUT TO MAKE SURE THAT THE
HEARTBREAK AND THE ANGER IS NOT
DISSIPATED OR LOST IN
LEGISLATIVE GRIDLOCK.
>> ALSO SAYING, THE STRONGEST
GUN CONTROL LAWS WON'T STOP ALL
ACTS OF VIOLENCE.
AND ON THE SUNDAY TALKS,
CONGRESSMAN CHAFITS, A
REPUBLICAN FROM UTAH, SAYS WE
NEED TO EXPLORE WHAT HE CALLS
THE INTERSECTION OF LETHAL
WEAPONS AND MENTAL HEALTH.
HE SAYS VIOLENCE AND THE MEDIA
ARE MAJOR FACTORS IN THIS
EQUATION.
>> WE HAVE TO DEAL WITH THE NEW
SOCIAL RAMIFICATIONS OF THE
BOMBARDMENT AND THE IMMEDIACY OF
THE SOCIAL INTERSECTION BETWEEN
VIOLENCE, THE REALISM IN GAMES
AND MOVIES, SOME YOUNG PEOPLE,
AS THEY ARE MAKING THE
TRANSITION FROM THE TEEN YEARS
INTO ADULTHOOD ARE NOT ABLE TO
MAKE THAT TRANSITION AND THERE
DOES NEED TO BE HELP.
WE ARE GOING TO NEED TO LOOK TO
FAMILIES AND COMMUNITIES AND
CHURCHES.
IT IS NOT A GOVERNMENT SOLUTION.
>> Reporter: THE CONGRESSWOMAN
SAYING TODAY, AND THESE ARE HER
WORDS -- WE NEED TO LOOK AT WHAT
DRIVES A CRAZY PERSON TO THIS
AND ENFORCE THE LAWS ON THE
BOOKS.
>> THANK YOU, STEVE.
>> WE ARE SLOWLY LEARNING MORE
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED INSIDE
SEASONED HOOK ALMOSTARY FROM
THOSE WHO WERE THERE.
SECOND GRADE TEACHER SAID SHE
WAS IN HER CLASSROOM, WHEN SHE
HEARD THE SHOOTER OPEN FIRE.
>> I HEARD WHAT SOUNDED LIKE
GLASS BROKE.
I WENT OUT TO SEE WHAT THAT WAS.
I REALIZED THAT IT WAS NOT
GLASS, IT WAS...
POSSIBLE GUNSHOTS.
I TURNED AROUND AND WENT BACK
INTO MY CLASSROOM AND CALLED FOR
MY TEACHER TO DO A LOCKDOWN.
I HOARDED MY KIDS TO A SAFE
CORNER, CALLED 911.
LISTENED TO THEIR INSTRUCTIONS
AND WAITED FOR HELP.
>> SHE SAID THEY GAVE THE
CHILDREN BOOKS TO READ WHILE
THEY WERE WAITING FOR THE ALL
CLEAR TO LEAVE THE CLASSROOM.
>> SIX-YEAR-OLD NOAH PAZZENER'S
LIFE WAS CUT SHORT ON FRIDAY.
ACCORDING TO HIS UNCLE, HE WAS
SMART AS A WHIP.
WHEN HIS MOTHER SAID I LOVE YOU,
HE WOULD SAY, NOT AS MUCH AS I
LOVE YOU.
HE CALLED HIS TWIN SISTER HIS
BEST FRIEND AND HE HAD AN OLDER
SISTER, SOPHIE.
THEY WERE NOT INJURED.
WE HAVE BEEN LEARNING MORE ABOUT
EACH OF THE VICTIMS.
YOU CAN GO TOfoxnews.com TO
READ ABOUT THEIR STORIES.
NORMALLY, THEY WOULD BE GEARING
UP FOR HOLIDAY FUN.
BUT NOW IT'S A COMMUNITY TRYING
TO COME TO TERPS WITH THE
UNIMAGINABLE.
A LIVE REPORT ON HOW THE PEOPLE
OF NEWTOWN ARE COPING.
AND WE WILL TALK TO THE FORMER
GOVERNOR AND ONE-TIME HOMELAND
SECRETARY, HE WAS INVOLVED IN
THE VIRGINIA TECH MASSACRE.
WHAT HE SAID ABOUT WHAT THE
SCHOOLS CAN LEARN FROM THE
TRAGEDY, NEXT.
>> I PRAY TO GOD IT'S GOING TO
HELP HEAL THESE PEOPLE WHO LOST
CHILDREN.
WE HAVE TWO YOUNG DAUGHTER, I
CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT IT MUST FEEL
LIKE.
>> YOU HAVE TO WATCH SOMETHING
SO LONG AND THEN HAVE YOU TO
COME OUT AND LAY OUT THE
FLOWERS, SAY A FEW PRAYERS.
[ Male Announcer ]
RED LOBSTER'S CRABFEST
ENDS SOON.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OURENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
TILL YOU FINISH YOUR VEGETABLES.
[ clock ticking ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THERE'S A BETTER WAY...
V8 V-FUSION.
VEGETABLE NUTRITION THEY NEED,
FRUIT TASTE THEY LOVE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
OR...TRY KIDS BOXES!
Uh...
Um...
Hm...
Umm...
Uh...
Oh !
The Windows Phone 8X
by HTC on Verizon.
It features easy
to navigate live tiles
that are simple
to customize.
Just pin what matters most
right to your homescreen.
Exclusively with Data Sense--
a feature that makes the most
of you plan.
Only on Verizon.
>> WE ARE
> SHANNON: THE WAKE OF THE
SHOOTING, CHURCHES IN SANDY HOOK
HAVE BECOME A PLACE OF SOLACE.
SEVERAL FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS
HAVE BEEN CONSOLED IN A CHURCH.
WE GO LIVE TO THE CHURCH, WHERE
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN FILING IN AND
OUT OF MASS ALL MORNING.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING, OR
GOOD AFTERNOON TO YOU.
DURING THIS TIME OF DESPAIR,
RESIDENTS ARE TRYING TO REMEMBER
THAT THERE IS GOOD IN THE WORLD
AS THEY STRUG TOLL MAKE SENSE OF
THE TRAGEDY.
SUNDAY MORNING CHURCH SERVICES
HAVE BECOME MEMORIAL SERVICES,
REMEMBERING 20 INNOCENT PERSON N
AND 6 DAAL WHO IS LOST THEIR
LIVES, MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS MEMOE
POPPED UP, MANY OF THEM READING,
PRAY FOR SANDY HOOK.
YOUNG PEOPLE ARE BEING
REMEMBERED, LIKE SIX-YEAR-OLD
EMILIE PARKER, HER HEART-WARMING
SMILE ONE OF THE MANY THINGS HER
FATHER WILL MISS.
>> I WAS TEACHING HER
PORTUGUESE.
OUR LAST CONVERSATION WAS IN
SHE -- SHE TOLD ME GOOD MORNING
AND -- ASKED HOW I WAS DOING.
I SAID I WAS DOING LIMP SHE SAID
SHE LOVED ME AND I GAVE HER A
KISS AND I WAS OUT THE DOOR.
>> Reporter: KIDS LOST MANY
PLAYMATES AND SOME OF THEIR
FAVORITE TEACHERS.
THIS THIRD GRADER, CARRIED A
POSTER, PAYING TRIBUTE TO HER
FIRST GRADE TEACHER, VICTORIA
SOTO.
>> SHE'S MY REALLY GOOD TEACHER.
>>URE YOUR FAVORITE.
>> MY FAVORITE TEACHER.
>> Reporter: SOME OF THE
PARENT WHO IS LOST THEIR
CHILDREN ARE MOURNING WITH
FELLOW NEIGHBORS IN THE PACKED
SERVICES.
DISHEARTENED PARENTS, TAKING A
BREAK FROM PLANNING FUNERALS FOR
LITTLE ONES.
MANY FEEL THEY HAVE NO WAY TO
HELP THE FAMILIES EXCEPT THROUGH
FAITH AND PRAYER.
PRESIDENT BARACK OBAMA IS
SCHEDULED TO COME TO THE AREA
LATER TODAY.
THIS IS THE FOURTH TIME HE HAS
GONE TO A TAJ IN MOURNING,
FOLLOWING A MASS SHOOTING.
> SHANNON: LIVE FROM THE CHURCH.
THANK YOU.
THE FRIDAY SHOOTING IS ONE OF
SEVERAL DEADLY SHOOTINGS AT
SCHOOLS HERE IN THE U.S., COMING
UP, WE WILL TALK TO FORMER
GOVERNOR AND ONE-TIME HOMELAND
SECURITY SECRETARY, TOM RIDGE
WHO, SAT ON THE REVIEW PANEL
THAT INVESTIGATED THE VIRGINIA
TECH SHOOTING.
WE WILL GET HOTDOGS TAKE ON WHAT
HAPPENED IN SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
>> MISINFORMATION IS POSTED ON
SOCIAL MEDIA SITES.
>> THERE HAS BEEN MISINFORMATION
COMING FROM PEOPLE POSING AS THE
SHOOTER IN THIS CASE, POSING,
USING OTHER I.D.s, MIMICKING
THIS -- THIS CRIME, CRIME SCENE.
> SHANNON: IN A PRESS CONFERENCE
THAT WRAPPED UP A SHORT TIME
AGO, CONNECTICUT POLICE
CAUTIONED NOT TO TRUST THE
MISINFORMATION THEY SAY IS BEING
SPREAD ONLINE, VIA SOCIAL MEDIA,
WARNING THAT POSTING THREATENING
MISINFORMATION IS A CRIME AND IT
WILL BE PROSECUTED AND
INVESTIGATED BY BOTH STATE AND
FEDERAL AUTHORITIES.
LATER TODAY, PRESIDENT
OBOTTOMMAL ADDRESS NEWTOWN AND
THE NATION IN A VIGIL FOR THE
NATION.
WE HAVE THE LATEST ON THE TOP
HEADLINES.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL SPEND
THE AFTERNOON, VISITING
PRIVATELY WITH FAMILY WHO IS
LOST LOVED ONES AND HE WILL
LEAVE WASHINGTON AT 3:00 P.M.
EASTERN TIME AND WILL SPEAK AT
THE NEWTOWN HIGH SCHOOL AT 7:00
THIS EVENING.
FOX CONFIRMS, THERE COULD BE
SOME MOVEMENT IN FISCAL CLIFF
TALKS.
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER HAS
OFFERED A PROPOSAL TO RAISE TAX
RATES FOR THOSE WHO EARN MORE
THAN $1 MILLION ANNUALLY.
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS NOT READY TO
SIGN ONTO THAT PROPOSAL AT THIS
POINT.
IN EGYPT, VOTERS RIGHTS GROUPS
ARE CALLING FOUL A
CONSTITUTIONAL DRAFT, SAYING THE
VOTE WAS MARRED BY VIOLATIONS.
THEY CLAIM THERE WASN'T ENOUGH
JUDICIAL OVERSIGHT AND SOME
WOMEN WERE PREVENTED FROM
VOTING.
THE MUSLIM BROTHERHOOD IS
CLAIMING AN EARLY VICTORY ON THE
ISLAMIC-BACKED CONSTITUTION.
SENATOR JOHN KERRY IS EXPECTED
TO BE NOMINATED TO BE THE NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE.
EARLY REPORTS SUGGEST THE
OFFICIAL ANNOUNCEMENT WILL COME
NEXT WEEK.
BUT PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS NOT
FINALIZED HIS PICKS FOR THE REST
OF THE NATIONAL SECURITY TEAM.
THOSE ARE THE TOP STORIES RIGHT
NOW.
BACK TO YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
FOCUSING ON THE HEROS IN THIS
TRAGEDY IS HELPING MANY PEOPLE
TO PROCESS WHAT HAPPENED AT
SANDY HOOK, ELEMENTARY.
LAST NIGHT, THERE WAS A MOVING
VIG NIL HONOR OF 60ORIA SOTO.
SHE HID HER STUDENTS IN
CUPBOARDSBOARDS AND CLOSETSES.
SHE DIED SHIELDING THE FRRN FROM
THE GUNMAN WITH HER OWN BODY,
ACTIONS THAT MANY AT THE SCHOOL
ARE CALLING HEROIC.
>> I DIDN'T KNOW HER AT ALL.
BUT I DON'T KNOW -- IT COULD
HAVE BEEN MY KID.
> SHANNON: THOSE WHO KNEW
VICTORIA SAY HER LIFE-SAVING
ACTIONS WERE NOT SURPRISING.
THAT SHE PUT HER CHILDREN 50 AND
WANT TO DO HER BEST FOR HEM.
THIS BRINGS BACK PAINFUL
MEMORIES OF A STUDENT ON A
RAMPAGE IN VIRGINIA TECH,
SHOOTING AND KILLING 32 PEOPLE,
WOUNDING 17 OTHERS AND THEN
KILLING HIMSELF.
FORMER HOMELAND SECURITY TOM
RIDGE WAS ON THE PANEL
INVESTIGATING THE MASSACRE AND
THE UNIVERSITYEE RESPONSE TO IT
AND FORMER GOVERNOR, THANK YOU
FOR JOINING US.
>> SAD TO JOIN YOU UNDER THESE
CIRCUMSTANCE, BUT IT'S AN
IMPORTANT CONVERSATION AND THE
ENTIRE COUNTRY HAS TO HAVE THIS
CONVERSATION.
IT'S ABOUT TIME.
> SHANNON: THERE ARE SO MANY
PORTIONS OF THE CONVERSATION TO
HAVE.
WE TALKED ABOUT THE FACT TAIN A
NUMBER OF SHOOTINGS ISSUE THERE
ARE SO MANY COMMON FACTORS WITH
THOSE WHO CARRIED OUT THE
CRIMES, MAYBE THAT'S A GOOD
PLACE TO START.
>>IC IT IS.
IF YOU LOOK AT HORRIFIC
INCIDENTS AND YOU PULL BACK AND
TAKE A LOOK AT THE PROFILE OF
THE ACTORS.
FIRST OF ALL, NONE OF THESE WERE
SPONTANEOUS EVENTS.
THEY WERE PLANNED.
MANY WERE PLANNED AND THE
KNOWLEDGE OF THE PLANNING WAS
KNOWN BY FELLOW STUDENT OR THEY
TALKED ABOUT THEIR SUICIDAL
TENDENCIES OR THEIR DESIRE TO
KILL PEOPLE TO FELLOW STUDENTS.
SO IT'S PREDICTABLE THATY WOOER
GOING TO BE TALKING ABOUT
ADDITIONAL GUN CONTROL
LEGISLATION.
IT IS FAR MORE COMPLICATED THAN
THAT -- NOT THAT WE SHOULDN'T --
BUT THE FACT REMAINS, THERE ARE
MULTIPLE LAYERS, IF WE HAVE A
SERIOUS CONVERSATION ABOUT
REDUCING THE RISK OF THIS
HAPPENING, WE BETTER START
DEALING WITH ALL THE LAYERS,
IT'S ABOUT PRIEFACY AND MENTAL
HEALTH COUNSELING AND ABERRANT
BEHAVIOR AND GETTING THE PEOPLE
THE HELP THEY NEED.
IT'S ABOUT STUDENTING TELLING
PARENT THEIR PARENTS OR
COUNSELORS THAT THEY HAVE HEARD
THE SELF-DESTRUCTIVE RUMBLINGS.
I KNOW A LOT OF PEOPLE DISAGREE
WITH ME, BUT I THINK THAT
VIOLENCE BEGETS VIOLENCE AND
HAVE YOU AN INDIVIDUAL WHO HAS
PERHAPS BEEN REJECTED, VILIFIED,
BULLIED, FEELS NOT PART OF THE
CROWD, THEY CAN LOSE THEMSELVES
IN A FANTASY WORLD OR A DIGITAL
WORLD.
SUDDENLY, THEIR SENSE OF REALITY
IS LIKE NOTHING YOU AND I COULD
EVER APPRECIATE.
> SHANNON: DO YOU THINK THAT
THERE IS A WAY TO BROACH THESE
TOPICS?
BECAUSE I WOULD IMAGINE EVERY
ONE OF USV HAS HAD SOMEONE IN
OUR LIVES, A FRIEND OR CO-WORKER
OR A NEIGHBOR THAT YOU KNOW
SOMETHING'S NOT RIGHT.
WE ARE HESITANT TO GET INVOLVED
TO INTRUDE ON SOMEONE'S PRIVACY,
BUT IT COULD MAKE ALL THE
DIFFERENCE.
WE KNOW ABOUT AN ALLEGED PLOT
BUSTED UP LAST WEEK WHEN THE
OFFICERS GOT THE WORD FROM
FEELINGO STUDENT WHO IS SAID
SOMETHING'S GOING WRONG WITH
THIS STUDENT.
HE IS SAYING THINGS THAT ARE
POTENTIALLY DEADLY.
>> IT IS TAKING A LONG TIME FOR
US CULTURALLY TO ACT WHEN WE SEE
FRIENDS STRUGGLING WITH
ALCOHOLISM.
WE DO ENCOURAGE THEM TO GET
INTERVENTION.
WE HAVE TO TAKE THE SAME
MIND-SET WITH THIS DISTORTED,
SELF-DESTRUCTIVE BEHAVIOR,
MANIFESTING ITSELF AND GET
INVOLVED.
A LEFT CONVERSATIONS DURING THE
HOLIDAY SEASON, COCKTAIL PARTIES
AND THE LIKE, WHEN ONE PIRNT
SAYS, HOW'S YOUR SON DOING -- I
DOUBT ANY OF THE PARENTS SAYS,
HE HAD A FEW MENTAL HEALTH
PROBLEMS WEERK HAVE HIM GOING TO
A THERAPIST.
WE ONLY RESPOND TO THE MENTAL
HEALTH CHALLENGES AFTER THE
FACTS AND FRANKLY, FAMILIES
IGNORE IT.
OR WE PUT THEM ON SEVERE
MEDICATION.
ONE OF THE STUDENTS IN THE
COLUMBINE SHOOTING WAS ON SEVERE
MEDICATION THAT COULD BE
CONTRIBUTED TO HIS AGGRESSIVE,
DESTRUCTIVE BEHAVIOR.
WE HAVE TO TAKE A 360-LOOK AT
THIS AND SENATOR LIEBERMAN IN A
VERY THOUGHTFUL WAY SAID WE
BETTER HAVE A COMMISSION BECAUSE
IT'S FAR MORE THAN A PRESS
CONFERENCE.
IT IS FAR MORE THAN A SINGLE
PIECE OF LEGISLATION IF WE ARE
GOING ON REDUCE THE RISK OF THIS
UPON HAING AGAIN.
> SHANNON: YOU INVESTIGATED WHAT
HAPPENED AT VIRGINIA TECH.
THIS IS AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE SETTINGS ARE DIFFERENT, BUT
IT'S A COMMONNALLITY OF SCHOOL.
>> AGAIN, YOU KNOW, IT'S -- THE
CLASSIC EXAMPLE, YOU DON'T WANT
TO TURN THE SCHOOL INTO A
FORTRESS.
THIS IS A SCHOOL, AS I
UNDERSTAND IT, THAT DID
EVERYTHING CONVEEFABLY POSSIBLE,
LIMIT THE ENTRANCE AND THE EXIT
WITH THE BUZZER.
THIS IS A SCHOOL, THE SCHOOL
GETS GREAT -- IT'S UNSPEAKABLE
TRAGEDY.
BUT ONE WONDERS WHAT HAPPENS IF
THEY DIDN'T HAVE LOCKDOWN FTHE
AIDE DIDN'T CALL 911.
IF THE SCHOOL DIDN'T YELL
LOCKDOWN AND THE HEROINE WHO
PROTECTED HER KIDS.
THERE IS SO MUCH YOU CAN DO.
THAT'S WHY WE WANT TO SAY, WE
WANT TO TRY TO RESPOND AS BEST
WE CAN.
WE DON'T WANT TO TURN OUR
SCHOOLED -- SCHOOLS INTO ARMED
FORTRESSES.
IT IS NOT JUST ACCESS TO
WEAPONS, BUT WHO GETS THEM AND
WHY.
THIS EYE KNOW THIS IS BASIC --
THIS IS BASIC.
CHILDREN ARE NOT BORN EVIL OR
VIOLENT.
BUT THEY MAY BEGIN WITH
PSYCHOLOGICAL DIFFICULTIES AND A
VARIETY OF INFLUENCES AND
EXPERIENCES TAKE THEM IN THAT
PATH.
WE HAVE TO ACCEPT THAT AND ALSO
UNDERSTAND THE IMPORTANCE OF
CULLURE, IMPORTANCE THE
INTERVENTION, IMPORTANCE OF
MENTAL HEALTH.
THERE WERE MANY LESSONS IN
VIRGINIA TECH, PRIVACY LAWS WERE
CONFUSED, THE MENTAL HEALTH
SYSTEM, THIS MAN HAD A
DETERIORATING MENTAL CONDITION,
PEOPLE KNEW ABOUT TNOBODY
RESPONDED TO IT.
THIS IS A LOT MORE THAN SENATOR
FEINSTEIN'S GOING TO DO
LEGISLATION WITH REGARD TO
REGULATIONS ON GUN CONTROL.
THAT'S AS PREDICTABLE AS THE SUN
COMING UP TOMORROW.
BUT THERE IS A LOT MORE TO DO
THEN THAN A SINGLE PIECE OF
LEGISLATION.
>>
> SHANNON: AND A RESPONSIBILITY.
>> HOMELAND SECURITY WAS A
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT.
IT WAS A NATIONAL MISSION.
WELL, THE SAFETY AND SECURITY OF
OUR KIDS AND OUR SCHOOLS ISN'T
THE MISSION OF ANY ONE
DEPARTMENT OR ANYBODY, AN
INDIVIDUAL, IT'S A COUNTRY'S
MISSION.
WE HAVE TO BE CLEAR IN OUR
THINKING AND WE HAVE TO GET AWAY
FROM THE NOTION THAT THERE IS
JUST A SINGLE WAY WE CAN REDUCE
THE THREAT OF THIS CONTINUING
VIOLENCE.
A LOT OF LESSONS LEARNED.
AFTER EVERY ONE OF THESE, WE
TALK ABOUT IT, VIRGINIA TECH, WE
TALKED ABOUT, AUROR ACCOMRADO,
WE TALKED ABOUT IT.
THE TIME FOR TALK IS OVER.
LET'S HAVE A NATIONAL
CONVERSATION AND REALLY TRY TO
ADDRESS SOME OF THE INDEMIC
PROBLEMS WITHIN OUR CULTURE.
> SHANNON: FORMER HOMELAND
SECRETARY, FORMER GOVERNOR,
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> GREAT TALKING WITH YOU.
>> Reporter: TEXAS, OREGON,
COLORADO, WISCONSIN, NOW
CONNECTICUT, WITH MASS SHOOTINGS
THIS YEAR ALONE.
WHY IS IT BECOMING TOO COMMON?
WE WILL TALK TO AUTHOR JOEL
ROSENBERG, ABOUT OUR MORAL AND
SPIRITUAL UNDERPINNINGS.
BUT THE LIST OF NAMES AND THEIR
TENDER AGES.
THE VICTIMS OF THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SHOOTING.
BLAM
I HAVE A COLD,
AND I TOOK NYQUIL,
BUT I'M STILL STUBBED UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus Liquid Gels
SPEEDS RELIEF
TO YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A DECONGESTANT
FOR YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
THANKS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
AND YOU LEARNED SOMETHING
ALONG THE WAY.
THIS IS THE AGE OF KNOWING
WHAT YOU'RE MADE OF.
SO, WHY LET
ERECTILE DYSFUNCTION
GET IN YOUR WAY?
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT VIAGRA.
20 MILLION MEN ALREADY HAVE.
ASK IF YOUR HEART
IS HEALTHY ENOUGH FOR SEX.
DO NOT TAKE VIAGRA IF YOU TAKE
NITRATES FOR CHEST PAIN;
IT MAY CAUSE AN UNSAFE DROP
IN BLOOD PRESSURE.
SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE
HEADACHE, FLUSHING,
UPSET STOMACH,
AND ABNORMAL VISION.
TO AVOID LONG-TERM INJURY,
SEEK IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
FOR AN ERECTION
LASTING MORE THAN FOUR HOURS.
STOP TAKING VIAGRA
AND CALL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU EXPERIENCE
A SUDDEN DECREASE OR LOSS
IN VISION OR HEARING.
THIS IS THE AGE
OF TAKING ACTION.
VIAGRA.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR.
SEE IF AMERICA'S
MOST PRESCRIBED ED TREATMENT
IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
I just served my mother-in-law
your Chicken Noodle soup
but she loved it so much...
I told her it was homemade.
Everyone tells
a little white lie now and then.
But now she wants
my recipe
[ clears his throat ]
[ softly ]
She's right behind me isn't she?
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
>> MATE GOD OF CONSOLATION TOUCH
THEIR HEARTS AND EASE THEIR PAIN
DURING THIS CHRISTMAS SEASON,
LET US BRING OURSELVES MORE
FERVENTLY TO PRAYER AND ACTS OF
PEACE.
TO THOSE WHO ARE AFFECTED BY
THIS TRAGEDY, MAY YOU HAVE
ABUNDANT BLESSINGS.
>> POPE BENEDICT OFFERING HIS
PRAYERS TO EVERYONE WHO LOST
LOVED ONES ON FRIDAY.
THE PONTIFF SAYINGY THAT HE IS
GRIEVING ALONG WITH THE
SECURITY.
SANDY HOOK WAS STRICT ON
BUT THE LOCKED DOORS AND THE
SECURITY DID NOT STOP THE
GUNMAN.
HOW CAN WE KEEP SCHOOLS SAFE.
>> ERIC:
>> Reporter: SCHOOL SECURITY
EXPERTS SAYING THERE NEEDS TO BE
A RETHINK IN LOCKDOWN
STRATEGIES.
IN MANY SCHOOL, ONLY
ADMINISTRATE ADMINISTRATORS CAN
ORDER THAT.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> THAT IS UNACCEPTABLE, IF ONLY
THE ADMINISTRATOR IS ALLOWED TO
DO
DO A LOCKDOWN, WE HAVE TO
EMPOWER AND TRAIN YOU TO DO A
LOCKDOWN.
ANYONE IN THE BUILDING WHO SEES
A DANGEROUS SITUATION SHOULD BE
ABLE TO CARRY OUT A LIFE-SAVING
FAMPGZ.
>> BY THAT, JANITORS,
MAINTINANCE PEOPLE, NON-TEACHERS
SHOULD BE ALLOWED TO MAINTAIN A
LOCKDOWN AND SECURITY EXPERTS
SAYING THAT THE SCHOOLS NEED TO
DO MONTHLY SECURITY DRILL,
EVACUATION DRILLINGS, SIMILAR TO
FIRE EVACUATIONS AND SCHOOLS
REALLY DO ALL THE TIME.
THEY ARE VERY FAMILIAR IN
CONDUCTING THOSE.
THEY ARE IMPROVING SECURITY IN
TERMS OF WHAT THE PARENTS AND
TEACHERS ARE THINKING.
YOU WOULD THINK THE PARENTS OR
TEACHERS WOULD BE CALLING FOR
TOUGHER SECURITY MEASURES.
BUT PEOPLE WE SPOKE TO
YESTERDAY, THE GENERAL PUBLIC,
GAVE US THESE RESPONSES.
>> FROM WHAT I SEE, MOST SCHOOLS
HAVE THE PROPER PROTOCOLS AND IT
WAS JUST AN UNFORTUNATE...
TRAGEDY.
>> SHORT OF LOCKING THEM IN,
THERE IS NOTHING YOU CAN DO.
>> THE PARENTS NEED TO MAKE SURE
THEY ARE TAKING CARE OF THEIR
KIDS.
IF YOUR KID IS NOT DOING WELL
AND THEY HAVE PSYCHOLOGICAL
ISSUES, YOU HAVE TO ADDRESS IT?
I KNOW, I MEAN, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT ELSE -- SCHOOLS CAN DO.
>> Reporter: NO ONE APPEARED
TO WANT TO BLAME THE SCHOOLS.
PARENTS VERY MUCH SAYING, DO YOU
KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON WITH YOUR
KIDS' MIND?
IT'S HARD TO POLICE THE THOUGHTS
OF PEOPLE.
THEY ARE TALKING NOW ABOUT
BETTER FUNDING FOR SECURITY IN
SCHOOLS.
FUNDING COMES FROM A NUMBER OF
FEDERAL AND STATE PROGRAMS, BUT
ONE THING THAT SECURITY EXPERTS
ARE POINTING OUT IS THAT THERE
NEEDS TO BE A COORDINATED
NATIONAL POLICY INFORMED THAT
ENSURES EVERYONE'S INVOLVED HERE
IN PROTECTING SCHOOLS, AND THAT
MEANS GOVERNMENT AND STATE AND
FEDERAL LEVEL AND EMERGENCY
SERVICES AND OF COURSE, PARENTS.
EVERYONE KNOWS WHAT HAPPENS IN
THE EVENT OF AN INCIDENT AND THE
RESPONSE TASHOULD HAVE TAKEN
AFTERWARDS.
> SHANNON: THANK YOU.
HEADING OUT TO WORSHIP SERVICE,
PEOPLE ARE TURNING TO THEIR
FAITH FOR COMFORT IN THE WAKE OF
THE TRAGDY.
JOINING US TO TALK ABOUT HOW TO
COPE, JOE ROSENBERG, WHO IS
AUTHOR OF IMPLOSION, CAN AMERICA
RECOVER FROM ITS SCMK SPIRITUAL
CHALLENGES IN TIME.
>> GOOD TO BE WITH YOU.
> SHANNON: I WANTED TO START BY
ASKING, BEING IN THE NEWS
BUSINESS MANY YEARS, I FEEL THAT
COVERING STORIES ON STATE,
LOCAL, NATIONAL LEVEL, THERE
SEEMS TO BE A DECREASE IN
RESPECT FOR HUMAN LIFE, AN
INCREASE IN VIOLENCE.
AND HOW CULLURALY HAVE WE
CHANGED?
>> WE ARE SEEING AN EPIDEMIC OF
VIOLENCE AND LAWLESSNESS, THE
DEMONSOF LAWLESSNESS AND
VIOLENCE SEEM TO BE UNLEASHED IN
THE LAST 50 YEARS.
LOOK AT 1960 TO NOW, VIOLENT
CRIME IN AMERICA HAS MORE THAN
DOUBLED.
IT'S COME DOWN FROM ITS WORST IN
THE LATE 80s AND EARLY TO
MID 90s.
BUT WE ARE TALKING ABOUT 1.2
MILLION VIOLENT CRIMES A YEAR.
ALMOST 15,000 MURDERS A YEAR.
AND THIS, AS HORRIBLE -- AND
THIS IS AMONGST THE MOST
HORRIBLE I HAVE EVER IMAGINED,
THIS IS THE 18th MASS MURDER
EVENT OF THIS YEAR.
AND THE YEAR ISN'T OVER.
> SHANNON: HAVE WE BECOME
UNTETHERED FROM OUR MORAL OR
SPIRITUAL, EVEN OUR FAMILY
BONDS, OUR COMMUNITY BONDS?
>> I THINK WE HAVE.
I THINK THAT'S ACTUALLY A
MISSING ELEMENT OF THE COVERAGE
SO FAR.
ALTHOUGH I HOPE, GOING FORWARD,
WE'LL TALK MORE ABOUT THE
SPIRITUAL ISSUES BECAUSE IN THE
END, THIS ISN'T PRIMARILY A GUN
CONTROL OR MENTAL HEALTH ISSUE,
THOSE ARE THE ISSUES THAT SHOULD
BE DISCUSSED.
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT THE MORAL
AND SPIRITUAL DISARMAMENT.
PEOPLE ARE DRIVING GOD OUT,
SAYING CHRIST SHOULDN'T BE IN
SCHOOLS.
MOST OF WHAT IS HAPPENING, WE
SAY THAT WE ARE CHRISTIAN, 85%
OF AMERICANS SAY THEY ARE
CHRISTIANS.
YET, WE ARE SEEING THIS
METASTASIZING OF VIOLENCE AND
EVIL IN OUR SOCIETY.
AND OUR KIDS ARE CONFUSED.
DOES GOD MATTER, BUT ONLY ON
SUNDAYS?
DOES IT MATTER DURING THE WEEK?
IS CHRIST IMPORTANT?
CAN HE CHANGE ME IF I AM SCPAD
LONELY?
CAN HE HELP ME?
WHAT WE ARE DRIVING GOID -- GOD
OUT OF SCHOOL, SOCIETY, COURT,
THE MEDIA.
DID AND THIS IS LEADING TO I
THINK, THE RISK OF MORAL AND
SPIRITUAL IMPLOSION IN OUR
COUNTRY ITCH VICOVERRED A NUMBER
OF CASES.
YOU ARE WELL AWARE OF THEM WHERE
PEOPLE WILL SAY RELIGION DOESN'T
HAVE A PLACE IN OUR PUBLIC
FORUM.
IT ISN'T SOMETHING THAT SHOULD
BE FORCED ON EVERYONE.
SOME PEOPLE BELIEVE IN DIFFERENT
GODS, HOW DO WE HAVE THIS
CONVERSATION?
>> THIS IS REALLY THE CHURCH'S
FAULT.
NOT IN THIS SPECIFIC INCIDENT.
I AM TALKING ABOUT THE GENERAL
CHURCH THAT THE -- GENERAL SENSE
THAT THE CHURCH IS GETTING WEAK.
340,000 CONGREGATIONS IN
LIGHTHOUSES, SHOWING PEOPLE THAT
JESUS IS THE WAY, THE TRUTH AND
THE LIFE AND NOBODY CAN GET TO
THE HOPE AND THE ENJOY OF THIS
LIFE, EXCEPT THROUGH CHRIST.
BUT A LOT OF THOSE LIGHTHOUSES
ARE TIME AND OR HAVE GONE OUT,
CONFUSED AMONGST THEMSELVES OVER
WHETHER CHRIST IS THE WAY, THE
TRUTH AND THE LIFE.
THERE NEEDS TO BE A REVIVAL IN
THE CHURCH TO SAY THAT THE
SCRIPTURES ACTUALLY OFFER HOPE
TO A SOCIETY, AS WELL AS
INDIVIDUALS AND FAMILIES THAT
ARE LOST AND ARE TRYING TO FIND
THE WAY.
> SHANNON: SO THE CHURCH NEEDED
TO STRENGTHEN ITSELF BEFORE IT
CAN MINISTER.
>> YOU PUT YOUR OXYGEN MASK ON
FIRST AND THEN YOU PUT THE MASK
ON THE ONE NEXT TO YOU.
A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE NOT
PREACHING THE GOSPEL -- IN OTHER
WORDS, PEOPLE ARE SAYING, WHAT'S
THE WAY FORWARD?
HOW DO WE HELP A SOCIETY THAT
HAS SO MANY KIDS THAT SEEM TOW
LOST, GOING TO VIOLENCE?
JESUS SAID, I AM THE WAY.
YEAH, YEAH.
WE DON'T WANT TO HEAR THAT.
HOW DO WE HELP KID WHO IS DON'T
KNOW THE TRUTH?
JESUS SAID, I AM THE TRUTH.
PEOPLE SAY, I DON'T WANT TO HEAR
THAT.
THE CHURCHES HAVE TO START --
AND THEN, YOU KNOW, WE CAN'T
EXPECT THE CULT TOWER DO WHAT
THE CHURCH ISN'T DOING.
THAT'S WHY WE NEED AN, I
REVIVAL.
> SHANNON: THIS IS AN IMPORTANT
TIME OF YEAR FOR RELIGIOUS
DISCUSSIONS.
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Reporter:
> SHANNON: THE FIRST ROUND OF
RESULTS ARE IN FROM A
CONTROVERSIAL REFERENDUM VOTE IN
EGYPT.
AFTER THE BREAK, WE GO LIVE TO
CAIRO.
AND CONTINUING COVERAGE OF THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTING,
FINING HOPE IN FAITH.
WE'LL TALK TO A TEAM OF REVEREND
BILLY GRAHAM'S CHAPLAIN SENT TO
HELP DEAL WITH THE TRAGEDY AND
FIND SOME HOPE.
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
>> THE MUSLIM BROTHER HOO IS
CLAIMING VICTORY ON AN
ISLAMIC-BACKED CONSTITUTIONAL
DRAFT.
EARLY REPORTS SUGGEST THAT THE
TURNOUT WAS LOW AND THERE MAY
HAVE BEEN PROBLEMS.
WE GO LIVE TO CAIRO FOR THE
LATEST.
>> Reporter: SHANNON, IT LOOKS
LIKE THE FOLKS IN FAVOR OF THAT
CONTROVERSIAL CONSTITUTION WILL
GET THEIR WAY.
THE VOTING THIS WEEKEND WAS THE
FIRST OF TWO ROUNDS, BUT
ACCORDING TO PRELIMINARY RESULT,
THE YES VOTE GOT 57%.
THE NO VOTE, 43%.
TURNOUT WAS OFF BY EGYPTIAN
STANDARDS AS THE OPPOSITION IS
CLAIMING WIDESPREAD
IRREGULARITIES AND THE
GOVERNMENT IS DISMAISES --
MISSING THE -- DISMISSING THE
CHARGES.
THE HEADQUARTERS OF AN
OPPOSITION SECULAR PARTY WAS
FIRE-BOMBED BY ISLAMISTS HERE IN
CAIRO OVERNIGHT, DESPITE 120,000
EGYPTIAN SOLDIERS OUT IN THE
STREETS.
MUHAMMAD MORSI AND THE MUZZ LOOM
BROTHERHOOD PARTY HAS BEEN
FAVORED.
SUPPORTERS SAY IT IS NEEDED TO
GAIN THE SUPPORT OF THE
REVOLUTION.
IN THE RURAL AREAS, THEY ARE
FAVORABLE TO THE CONSERVATIVE
ISLAMISTS, SO IT SEEMS THAT THE
CONSTITUTION WILL GO THROUGH.
THERE IS A CHANCE TO MODIFY THE
CONSTITUTION, AFTER THE FACT.
THERE WILL BE NEW ELECTIONS FOR
A NEW PARLIAMENT AFTER THAT.
BUT IT APPEARS THAT THE
ISLAMISTS WILL REMAIN IN CHARGE
THAT.
, SHANNON, PRESENTS THE
POSSIBILITY OF MORE VIOLENCE IN
THE STREETS, ALSO PRESENTS THE
POSSIBILITY THAT AN ISLAMIST
WILL HAVE TO TRY TO RUN THIS
COUNTRY.
> SHANNON: GREAT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
AS WE ANXIOUSLY AWAIT ANSWERS TO
THE HORRIFIC SHOOTING IN SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY, POLICE IN
CONNECTICUT ARE ISSUING WARNINGS
TO SOCIAL MEDIA USERS.
WE WILL TELL YOU MORE ABOUT THAT
AFTER THIS BREAK.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
SOMETHING MADE YOUR JAW DROP?
CAMPBELL'S HAS 24 NEW SOUPS
THAT WILL MAKE IT DROP OVER,
AND OVER AGAIN.
♪
FROM JAMMIN' JERK CHICKEN,
TO CREAMY GOUDA BISQUE.
SEE WHAT'S NEW FROM CAMPBELL'S.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
>> THE SCHOOL WAS FORCIBLY
ENTERED THE SCHOOL FACILITY
ITSELF, OKAY, ENCOUNTERED --
JUST ENCOUNTERED
STAFF,STUDENTS AND THE TRAGEDY
OCCURRED.
>> Shannon: THE INVESTIGATION
CONTINUES IN THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL SHOOTING AS MILLIONS OF
AMERICANS HAD RELIGIOUS
SERVICES TODAY MANY OF THEM
ASKING THEMSELVES THE SAME HE
QUESTION, WHY.
THE PRESIDENT PREPARES TO
PERFORM ONE OF HIS SADDEST
DUTIES, COMFORTING AMERICANS
IN THE FACE OF A NATIONAL
TRAGEDY.
I'M SHANNON BREAM, HOUR NUMBER
TWO OF AMERICA'S HEADQUARTERS
STARTS WITH PETER DOOCY IN
NEWTOWN WHERE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE WRAPPED UP A NEWS
CONFERENCE HOURS AGO.
PETER?
>> SHANNON, 20 SANDY HOOK
FIRST GRADER ALSO NEVER GET TO
GO BACK TO CLASS.
NOW WE ARE HEARING THAT THE
TOWN IS GOING TO KEEP THE
SURVIVING STUDENTS TOGETHER
JUST MAYBE AT A DIFFERENT
SCHOOL.
I WOULD FIND IT VERY DIFFICULT
FOR THEM TO DO THAT.
CERTAINLY, IT'S ONE OF THE
THINGS THEY ARE GOING TO HAVE
TO LOOK INTO.
WE WANT TO KEEP THESE KIDS
TOGETHER.
THEY NEED SUPPORT OF EACH
OTHER.
>> CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
ABOUT ONE HOUR AGO TOLD
REPORTERS TO AVOID
MISINFORMATION ON SOCIAL MEDIA
AND WARNED THAT WHOEVER IS
POSTING THINGS LIKE FAKE
ACCOUNTS PRETENDING TO BE THE
SHOOTER IS GOING TO BE
PROSECUTED BY STATE AND
FEDERAL AUTHORITIES.
NOW, POLICE DID DECLINE TO
PROVIDE A TIME LINE ON
FRIDAY'S EVENTS ALTHOUGH THEY
DID SAY ONCE THE INVESTIGATION
IS COMPLETE WE WILL GET SOME
KIND OF A TIME LINE FROM THEM.
WE DID HEAR TODAY FROM
CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR DANO
MALOY AND HE DESCRIBED HIS
UNDERSTANDING OF THE
CIRCUMSTANCES THAT LED TO THE
SHOOTER'S SUICIDE.
>>
>> WE SURMISE IT WAS DURING
THE SECOND CLASSROOM EPISODE
THAT HE HEARD RESPONDERS
COMING AND APPARENTLY AT THAT
DECIDED TO TAKE HIS OWN LIFE.
>> AND OFF CAMERA AFTER THE
BRIEFING AN HOUR AGO PAUL
VANCE WITH THE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE SAID THAT THERE
ARE TWO SUFFER ADVISORS.
TWO ADULT SURVIVORS OF
FRIDAY'S SHOOTING.
WE DON'T KNOW WHO THE SECOND
SURVIVOR IS.
WE HAD HEARD INITIALLY THAT
THERE WAS ONLY ONE PERSON
BEING TREATED AT A LOCAL
HOSPITAL FOR GUNSHOT WOUNDS.
WE ARE NOW HEARING THAT THERE
IS A SECOND PERSON WHO
SURVIVED.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT KIND OF
INJURIES THEY HAVE.
WE DON'T KNOW AT THIS POINT IF
THEY HAVE BEEN RELEASED.
WE WILL TRY TO TRACK THAT DOWN
AND KEEP YOU UPDATED.
BACK TO YOU.
>> Shannon: THANKS FOR THE
UPDATES, PETER.
FOR MORE INSIGHT ON THE
INVESTIGATION, WE ARE JOINED
BY FORMER HOMICIDE DETECTIVE
AND FOX NEWS CONTRIBUTOR ROD
WHEELER.
THANK YOU FOR COMING IN TODAY.
>> GOOD TO BE HERE.
>> Shannon: I WANT TO START
WITH THE INFORMATION PETER HAD
THERE.
IT IS RELATIVELY NEW TO US
THAT THERE WERE TWO ADULT
SURVIVORS.
HOW WHAT THEY DID OR DIDN'T
SEE.
HOW CRITICAL COULD THEY BE IN
PIECING TOGETHER THESE EVENTS?
>> THEY WILL BE VERY CRITICAL.
I GUARANTEE THEY HAVE BEEN AND
WILL BE VERY CRITICAL IN THIS
EGGS HAVE A.
THINK 'IT, THESE ARE ADULTS,
EITHER IT'S A GOOD POSSIBILITY
THAT MAYBE THEY EVEN
RECOGNIZED WHO THIS GUY WAS
BUT THEY CAN AT LEAST PROVIDE
THE POLICE WITH SOME ABSOLUTE
INFORMATION.
I THINK THEY ARE GOING TO BE
VERY CRITICAL THROUGH THE THIS
ENTIRE INVESTIGATION.
>> POLICE HAVE SHARED VERY
LITTLE WHAT THEY COULD WITH US
SO FAR.
BUT YOU ARE VERY EXPERIENCED.
IS THERE ANYTHING THAT YOU
HAVE HEARD SO FAR, ANY CLUES,
THINGS THAT CATCH YOUR
ATTENTION AS A FORMER
DETECTIVE?
>> YES.
ACTUALLY THERE HAS BEEN A
NUMBER OF CLUES THAT I HAVE
PICKED UP ON, ESPECIALLY ON
FRIDAY, SHANNON THERE WAS ONE
PARTICULAR CLUE THAT I PICKED
UP ON, ACTUALLY WAS BROUGHT TO
MY ATTENTION BY NEIL CAVUTO.
HE ASKED ME A QUESTION ABOUT
SOMETHING.
REAL QUICKLY WHAT HE SAID YOU
KNOW, THE SUSPECT HE HAD HIS
BROTHER'S DRIVER'S LICENSE ON
HIM.
REMEMBER, THAT WAS EVEN
ANNOUNCED.
BUT IF YOU WILL RECALL THE
POLICE THOUGHT THEY WERE
LOOKING FOR TWO SUSPECTS.
REMEMBER?
BECAUSE THEY HAD THIS ONE GUY.
NOW HIS BROTHER'S NAME IS
RYAN.
THAT'S WHO THEY THOUGHT THEY
HAD.
AT THE SAME TIME THEY THOUGHT
THEY WERE LOOKING FOR ANOTHER
PERSON, ADAM.
BUT ACTUALLY THIS WAS ADAM,
THE BAD GUY.
WHO APPARENTLY SOMEONE AT THAT
SCHOOL MUST HAVE RECOGNIZED
THIS PERSON AS BEING ADAM.
THE PERSON WHO WAS DOING THE
SHOOTING.
IN ADDITION TO THAT, IF YOU
KNOW THE SECURITY SYSTEM HAD
RECENTLY BEEN UPGRADED AT THE
SCHOOL.
I DON'T THINK IT'S A
CONSEQUENCE, SHANNON THAT THAT
HAPPENED.
I THINK THIS GUY HAD
PREVIOUSLY MADE A THREAT OF
SOME TYPE TO SOMEONE AT THAT
SCHOOL AND THAT'S WHY HE DID
IT.
THE OTHER QUESTION FOR THE DAY
IS, WHEN WAS THE MOTHER
ACTUALLY KILLED?
NOW, WE KNOW HER BODY WAS
FOUND ON FRIDAY MORNING.
BUT WHEN WAS SHE KILLED?
AND I CAN TELL YOU LATER ON
BECAUSE IT'S GOING TO TAKE
SOME TIME BECAUSE THAT'S
SIGNIFICANT IN THIS
INVESTIGATION IF SHE WAS
KILLED A DAY OR TWO PRIOR TO
THE SHOOTING ON FRY PLAY.
PEOPLE HAVE HAD SO MANY
QUESTIONS ABOUT.
THERE IS JUST NO GOOD ANSWER
FOR WHY SOME INNOCENT CHILDREN
AND INNOCENT ADULTS EITHER.
BUT YOU ARE SAYING YOU THINK
HE MAY HAVE HAD SOME KIND OF
CONNECTION WITH THIS
PARTICULAR SCHOOL?
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
HE HAD TO HAVE A CONNECTION
WITH THE SCHOOL.
WHY?
BECAUSE SHOOTERS SUCH AS THIS,
THEY SELECT THEIR TARGETS,
BELIEVE IT OR NOT, THESE
AREN'T JUST RANDOM EVENTS
WHERE SOMEBODY IS GOING TO
WAKE UP ONE MORNING AND SAY
I'M GOING TO GO TO IT A SCHOOL
AND SHOOT 26 PEOPLE.
THEY PICK THEIR TARGETS FOR A
REASON.
WHETHER IT WAS A BERNE.
A LOT OF TIMES RELATED TO A
DOMESTIC SITUATION.
THEY SPECIFICALLY CHOOSE THEIR
TARGETS.
NOW, A WILL THE OF PEOPLE HAVE
BEEN ASKING, SHANNON, WHY WE
KILL HIS MOTHER?
REAL QUICKLY, I THINK THE
MOTHER, SHANNON, WAS IN THE
PROCESS OF HAVING HIM
PROBATED.
PROBATED MEANS THAT THIS GUY
HAS SOME KIND OF MENTION
PROBLEMS.
HE DOESN'T WANT TO GO TO THE
HOSPITAL.
HE DOESN'T WANT TO TAKE HIS
MEDICATION.
SO A FAMILY MEMBER HAS TO BE
THE ONE TO INITIATE THE
PROCESS SO THE POLICE CAN COME
OUT AND GET HIM.
I THINK HE FELT LIKE HIS
MOTHER WAS BETRAYING HIM.
THAT'S WHY HE KILLED HIS
MOTHER.
I THINK THAT'S WHY HE WENT TO
THE SCHOOL TO SOMEWHAT GET
EVEN WITH THE FOLKS AT THE
SCHOOL.
>> Shannon: OKAY.
HOW LONG WILL IT TAKE, DO YOU
THINK, BEFORE PUBLICLY WE WILL
HAVE SOME OF THESE PUZZLE
PIECES TO KNOW IF THESE
THEORIES ARE ON THE RIGHT
TRACK?
>> IT COULD TAKE AT LEAST A
WEEK IF NOT LONGER.
I THINK THE POLICE ALREADY
KNOW MOST OF THE ANSWERS TO
AWFUL THESE THINGS I'M SAYING.
BUT THEY HAVE TO BE VERY
CAUTIOUS RIGHT NOW.
THIS IS STILL A CRIMINAL
INVESTIGATION EVEN THOUGH WE
HAVE THE SUSPECT, IS HE DEAD.
THEY STILL HAVE TO DO THEIR
DUE DILIGENCE.
IT'S GOING TO TAKE A WEEK OR
LONGER BEFORE THEY COME OUT
AND EVERYTHING THAT'S GOING
ON.
>> Shannon: POSSIBLE BEFORE
THEY PUT TOGETHER THE PIECES
OF THIS THAT THERE ARE LESSONS
THAT POLICE CAN THEN SHARE TO
HELP PREVENT OTHER TRAGEDIES
SIMILAR TO THIS?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
UNFORTUNATELY WE LEARN THE
HARD WAY IN THIS COUNTRY.
OBVIOUSLY WE LEARNED FROM
COLUMBINE.
WE LEARNED FROM THE AURORA,
COLORADO SHOOTING.
WE'RE GOING TO LEARN FROM
THIS.
THAT COMMUNITY, WE AS A
NATION, WE WILL MOVE ON FROM
THIS.
WE WILL BECOME STRONGER AND
HOPEFULLY PREVENT THESE
HORRIFIC THINGS FROM HAPPENING
AGAIN.
>> ROD WHEELER, ALWAYS GOOD TO
SEE YOU, THANK YOU.
>> GOOD TO HE SUE, TOO
SHANNON.
>> Shannon: THE DAD OF THE
6-YEAR-OLD EMILY PARKER WAS
ONE OF THE FIRST PARENTS TO
SPEAK OUT PUBLICLY ABOUT THE
SHOOTING.
HE DESCRIBES HIS DAUGHTER AS A
HAPPY LITTLE GIRL WHO LIKED TO
MAKE CARDS AND ALMOST ALWAYS
CARRIED COLORED PENCILS OR
MARKERS.
SHE SAID SHE LOVED HER LITTLE
SISTERS AND CHEERING UP HER
SAD FRIENDS.
HE DESCRIBED HIS LAST MOMENTS
WITH HIS OLDEST DAUGHTER
FRIDAY MORNING.
THEY HAD BEEN LEARNING TO
SPEAK PORTUGUESE.
SHE TOLD HIM THAT SHE LOVED
HIM AND HE GAVE HER A KISS.
>> MY DAUGHTER, EMILY, WOULD
BE ONE OF THE FIRST ONES TO BE
STANDING AND GIVING HER LOVE
AND SUPPORT TO ALL THOSE
VICTIMS.
BECAUSE THAT'S THE TYPE OF
PERSON THAT SHE IS.
NOT BECAUSE OF ANY PARENTING
THAT MY WIFE AND I WOULD HAVE
DONE BUT BECAUSE THOSE ARE THE
GIFTS GIVEN TO HER BY HER
HEAVENLY FATHER.
>> PARKER EXPRESSED SYMPATHY
FOR THE FAMILY OF THE SHOOTER.
HE SENT LOVE FROM HIS FAMILY
TO THEIRS.
IF YOU ARE LOOKING TO HELP A
NUMBER OF MEMORIAL FUNDS HAVE
BEEN SET UP FOR THE SANDY HOOK
VICTIMS AND SURVIVORS.
THE UNITED WAY OF WESTERN
CONNECTICUT HAS SET UP THE
SANDY HOOK SUPPORT FUND.
LEARN HOW TO DONATE THROUGH
THEIR WEB SITE.
NEWTOWN MEMORIAL FUND IS BEING
CREATED IN ADDITION TO HELPING
THOSE AFFECTED DIRECTLY BY THE
TRAGEDY.
THE FUND IS HOPING TO POSSIBLY
BE ABLE TO SET UP A
SCHOLARSHIP.
AND THE NEWTOWN YOUTH AND
FAMILY SERVICES SAYS ANY
DONATIONS MADE TO THE
ORGANIZATION WILL GO DIRECTLY
TO THE VICTIMS OF THE
SHOOTING.
THE AMERICAN RED CROSS, OF
COURSE, IS THERE ON THE GROUND
OFFERING FOOD AND WATER AS
WELL AS GRIEF COUNSELING.
THOSE ARE JUST A FUTURECAST
ORGANIZATIONS TRYING TO HELP
OUT IF YOU WANT TO ASSIST THEM
IN THAT EFFORT.
ONE OF THE MANY PEOPLE LOOKING
TO HONOR VICTIMS IS NFL PLAYER
VICTOR CRUISE.
6-YEAR-OLD JACK PINTO WAS
REPORTEDLY A HUGE NEW YORK
GIANTS FAN.
HIS FAVORITE PLAYER WAS CRUZ.
CRUZ TWEET ADD PHOTO OF HIS
GLOVES AND CLEATS.
HE HAS WRITTEN PINTO'S NAME ON
THEM.
IS HE GOING TO WEAR THEM TODAY
IN THE GAME AGAINST THE
ATLANTA FALCONS.
THE ENTIRE LEAGUE WILL OBSERVE
MOMENTS OF SILENCE BEFORE
TODAY'S GAMES.
WELL SECRETARY OF STATE
HILLARY CLINTON WILL NOT
TESTIFY AT THIS WEEK'S
BENGHAZI HEARINGS ON CAPITOL
HILL FOLLOWING NEWS FROM THE
STATE DEPARTMENT THAT SHE FELL
ILL AND SUFFERED A CONCUSSION
THIS WEEK.
WILL SHE EVENTUALLY TESTIFY
AFTER SHE RECOVERS?
CONGRESSMAN HENRY, A DEMOCRAT
FROM TEXAS AND MATT THORN
BERRY A REPUBLICAN ALSO FROM
TEXAS JOIN US WITH THEIR
REACTIONS TO THAT NEWS AND
MUCH MORE THIS WEEK.
WELCOME TO YOU BOTH.
CONGRESSMAN CLARE.
I WILL START WITH YOU.
IF THERE IS ANYTHING YOU WOULD
LIKE TO SHARE IN RESPONSE TO
THE CONNECTICUT TRAGEDY?
>> FIRST OF ALL I JUST HAVE TO
SAY MY PRAYERS AND MY
SYMPATHIES TO THE FAMILIES.
IT HAS TO BE A VERY DIFFICULT
TIME.
ESPECIALLY RIGHT BEFORE
CHRISTMAS, SO, AGAIN, MY
PRAYERS TO ALL OF THE FAMILIES
AND THE FIRST RESPONDERS
THERE.
>> Shannon: CONGRESSMAN THORN
BERRY TO YOU AS WELL?
>> ALL OF OUR THOUGHTS AND
PRAYERS ARE FOCUSED ON THOSE
WITH CONNECTICUT.
I HAVE QUOTE TO SAY I AM TRULY
AMAZED AT THE POISE AND THE
GRACE OF THAT FATHER UP IN
CONNECTICUT.
I THINK THE WAY HE PROCHED
THIS IS A GOOD LESSON FOR ALL
OF WHEN YOU SAY WE FACE
DIFFICULT CIRCUMSTANCES.
VERY INSPIRING.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
WELL, LET'S TURN TO THE
BUSINESS OF THE DAY OR OF THIS
WEEK I SHOULD SAY.
CONGRESSMAN THERE WILL BE
HEARINGS ON BOTH HOUSE AND
SENATE SIDE ON BENGHAZI.
SECRETARY CLINTON WON'T BE
PRESENT.
ARE YOU CONFIDENT YOU CAN
ANSWER ANSWERS FROM THOSE IN
HER PLACE?
>> AGAIN, I'M SURE THERE IS
SOMEBODY THERE THAT CAN
TESTIFY.
I KNOW THEY WANTED TO HEAR
FROM SECRETARY CLINTON BUT
UNFORTUNATELY SHE COULD NOT DO
IT.
I HOPE SHE GETS BETTER.
BUT, AGAIN, THERE WILL BE
OTHER FOLKS THAT CAN ANSWER
THAT QUESTION.
AGAIN, THIS IS NOT THE ONLY
HEARING.
ERE CAN BE OTHER HEARINGS IN
THE FUTURE, ALSO.
>> AND, CONGRESSMAN THORN
BERRY, HOW ABOUT YOU?
I KNOW THERE WOULD WILL BE A
CLOSED BRIEFING FOR SOME
MEMBERS.
ALSO THE PLUCK HEARINGS DO YOU
THINK YOU WILL MAKE PROGRESS
THIS WEEK?
>> I THINK WE WILL MAKE
PROGRESS.
THERE ARE STILL A THE OF
UNANSWERED QUESTIONS.
SOME OF THOSE ISSUES INVOLVE
SECURITY PREPARATIONS BEFORE
THE ATTACK SOME OF THOSE
QUESTIONS INVOLVE WHO DID WHAT
DURING THE ATTACK.
SOME OF THOSE QUESTIONS
INVOLVE THE POLITICAL SPIN OR
THE WAY IT WAS PORTRAYED AFTER
THE ATTACK.
I THINK THIS WEEK IS REALLY
FOCUSED ON THE PREPARATIONS
BEFORE THE ATTACK.
THERE IS GOING TO BE REPORT OF
A COMMISSION AND THEY WILL
TELL US WHAT THEY FOUND.
BUT AT SOME POINT I THINK IT'S
UNDERSTANDABLE THAT THE
FOREIGN AFFAIRS COMMITTEE AND
THE HOUSE WOULD WANT TO HEAR
FROM THE SECRETARY OF STATE
DIRECTLY ABOUT DIPLOMATIC
SECURITY GENERALLY AND ABOUT
THE SITUATION IN LIBYA IN
PARTICULAR IT.
>> THERE ARE ALSO ALONG WITH
THE INTERNATIONAL ISSUES THAT
YOU WERE LOOKING INTO,
DOMESTIC ISSUES AS WELL, MOST
NOTABLY THE FISCAL CLIFF
THAT'S COMING.
CONGRESSMAN, I WANT TO GET
YOUR REACTION TO REPORTS LAST
NIGHT THAT HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER HAS INDICATED THAT HE
MAY BE OKAY WITH RAISING TOP
RATES ON THOSE WHO EARN A
MILLION DOLLARS OR MORE.
THIS EXCHANGE FOR SOME SERIOUS
CUTS ELSEWHERE.
>> AGAIN, LOOK, WE HAVE TO GET
TOGETHER, BOTH DEMOCRATS AND
REPUBLICANS, WE HAVE TO GET
TOGETHER DO THIS FOR THE GOOD
OF THE COUNTRY.
IT'S DIFFICULT.
I NO THOUGH IT IS.
I VOTED FOR THE EXTENSION OF
THE GEORGE BUSH TAX CUTS.
THIS IS SOMETHING WE HAVE TO
DO BECAUSE THEY ARE ALL
EXTENDING THE GEORGE BUSH TAX
CUTS WERE ONLY TEMPORARY AND,
OF COURSE, WE HAVE NOW GOT THE
SAYS QUESTIONS STATION.
WE HAVE TO COME TOGETHER AS
DEMOCRATS AND REPUBLICANS AND
I THINK WE DID TOO THIS IT.
>> Shannon: CONGRESSMAN THORN
BERRY AS A REPUBLICAN ARE YOU
OKAY WITH THAT DEAL?
I ASKED YOUR COLLEAGUE
CONGRESSMAN PETE KING EARLIER,
HE SAID HE WOULD BE ON BOARD
WITH WHATEVER THE SPEAKER
NEGOTIATED.
IS THAT TRUE FOR YOU, ALSO?
>> I THINK ALL OF US SUPPORT
THE SPEAKER IN HAVING ONE
NEGOTIATOR.
BUT ETCH AUTO OF US IS GOING
TO HAVE TO EVALUATE WHATEVER
WE -- IS PRESENT TO US FOR A
VOTE.
WE CAN'T KNOW THAT UNTIL WE
SEE IT.
I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT TO JUST
EMPHASIZE ONE NUMBER WITH ALL
THE BLIZZARD OF NUMBERS GOING
AROUND, ONE NUMBER IS 20.6.
SINCE THE END OF WORLD WAR II,
TOTAL TAX REVENUE COMING INTO
THE GOVERNMENT HAS NEVER BEEN
MORE THAN 20.6.
AND, YET, SPENDING IS MORE
LIKE 24% OF OUR GROSS DOMESTIC
PRODUCT.
THE POINT IS WHATEVER YOU DO
ON TAXES, AND THERE MAY WELL
HAVE TO BE SOME FLEXIBILITY ON
IT.
BUT WHATEVER DO YOU ON TAXES,
IF YOU DON'T ADDRESS SPENDING,
WE'RE NOT GOING TO ADDRESS THE
DEFICIT AND DEBT.
>> CONGRESSMAN THORN BERRY,
THANK YOU BOTH FOR YOUR TIME
TODAY, WE APPRECIATE IT?
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> WELL, IT DOES LOOK LIKE
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER IS
SIGNALING SOME MOVEMENT IN THE
STALLED FISCAL CLIFF TALKS.
MOLLY HENNEBERG IS FOLLOWING
THE STORY AND JOINS US LIVE
HERE IN WASHINGTON WITH MORE.
HELLO, MOLLY.
>> HI, SHANNON.
THE FISCAL CLIFF TALK HAS
QUIETED DOWN IN WASHINGTON IN
VIEWFT CONNECTICUT SCHOOL
SHOOTING THERE ARE STILL
NEGOTIATIONS GOING ON QUIETLY
BEHIND THE SCENES.
PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS REJECTED
THE REPUBLICANS MOST RECENT
PROPOSAL AT LEAST FOR NOW.
REPUBLICANS OFFERED A DEAL
THAT WOULD RAISE TAXES ON
AMERICANS MAKING OVER
$1 MILLION A YEAR.
IN EXCHANGE FOR DEEPER
SPENDING CUTS.
THAT WAS A NO-GO FOR PRESIDENT
OBAMA.
HE WANTS TO RAISE TAXES ON
THOSE MAKING MORE THAN
$250,000.
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER
OFFERED THE LATEST PROPOSAL ON
FRIDAY SHOWING SOME
FLEXIBILITY WITHIN THE G.O.P.
ON TAX HIKES.
REPUBLICANS SAY THE COUNTRY
HAS TO GET SPENDING UNDER
CONTROL.
IN ORDER TO GET THE NATIONAL
DEBT UNDER CONTROL.
ESPECIALLY WHEN IT COMES TO
ENTITLED SPENDING ON THINGS
LIKE MEDICARE AND SOCIAL
SECURITY.
BOEHNER HAS PREVIOUSLY
PROPOSED INCREASING THE
ELIGIBILITY AGE FOR MEDICARE
AND LOWERING COST OF LIVING
ADJUSTMENTS FOR SOCIAL
SECURITY.
HOUSE REPUBLICANS SAY THEY'RE
HOPEFUL.
>> HE IS OUR LEADER.
IS HE NEGOTIATING.
WE ARENER GOING TO GET THE
PERFECT DEAL.
I'M CONFIDENT THAT JOHN WILL
GET THE BEST DEAL THAT WE CAN.
>> AND WHILE THE PRESIDENT HAS
SHOWN SOME WILLINGNESS TO
DISCUSS THINGS LIKE RAISING
THE MEDICARE ELIGIBILITY AGE,
HIS LEFT WING IS ALREADY
SIGNALING THEY WON'T STAND FOR
IT.
HOUSE MINORITY LEADER NANCY
PELOSI SAID LAST WEEK THAT
RAISING THE MEDICARE AGE,
QUOTE:  DOESN'T WORK.
IT DOESN'T HAVE PLUCK SUPPORT,
IT'S UNFAIR.
AND IT DOESN'T LOWER HEALTH
EXPENDITURES.
THE PRESIDENT WAS SCHEDULED TO
TRAVEL TO MAINE THIS WEEK TO
PUSH FOR HIS FISCAL CLIFF
PLAN.
THAT TRIP HAS BEEN CANCELLED
BECAUSE OF THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
SHANNON?
>> MOLLY, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
ALL RIGHT.
WE WANT TO GIVE YOU A CHANCE
TO SPEAK OUT ON SPEAKER
BOEHNER'S PLAN.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
IS THIS PROMISING PROGRESS OR
SHOULD HE STAND HIS GROUND?
FOR YOUR ANSWERS TO ACT ANHQDC
OR AT SHANNON BREAM OR WE WILL
READ SOME OF THEM LATER IN HAD
HOUR.
LAST MONTH NEARLY 2,000
FEDERAL REGULATIONS HAVE BEEN
POSTED BY THE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION BUT IT'S BEEN
MORE THAN A YEAR SINCE THE
ADMINISTRATION REPORTED THE
ECONOMIC IMPACT OF THOSE
REGULATIONS TO CONGRESS AS
REQUIRED BY LAW.
ISSUES AND HOW MUCH IT COULD
COST YOU AFTER THIS BREAK.
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a
Droid Incredible 4G LTE
by HTC for $49.99.
>> IT HAS BEEN MORE THAN A
YEAR SINCE THE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION COMPLIED WITH A
LAW THAT REQUIRES FEDERAL
AGENCIES TO PLUCKILY REPORT
PROPOSED REGULATIONS THAT WILL
HAVE A SIGNIFICANT ECONOMIC
IMPACT DIRECTLY TO CONGRESS.
NOW, THOUGH THAT HASN'T
HAPPENED.
WE KNOW THAT OVER JUST THE
LAST 90 DAYS, 5994 PROPOSED
REGULATIONS HAVE BEEN ISSUED.
AND THAT'S ACCORDING TO THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT'S OWN WEB
SITE.
JOINING US NOW TO TALK ABOUT
REGULATION NATION THIS WEEK.
DIRECTOR OF REGULATORY POLICY
AT THE AMERICAN ACTION FORUM.
SAM, THANKS FOREVER COMING IN
TODAY.
>> THANKS FOR HAVING ME.
>> YOUR ORGANIZATION DOES A
GOOD JOB OF TRACKING HOW MANY
REGULATIONS ARE OUT THERE.
HOW MUCH IT'S GOING TOst DO.
THE REAL IMPACT OF IT.
NOW ALL THESE REGULATIONS
GENERALLY GO THROUGH THE WHITE
HOUSE TO BE VETTED IN SOME WAY
BEFORE THEY COME OUT.
A LOT OF THEM HAVE GOTTEN
STUCK THERE THIS YEAR.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
>> THERE IS DEFINITELY A
REGULATORY LAW JAM.
WE LOOKED AT A SIMILAR PERIOD
IN 2004 WHEN THERE WAS A
RE-ELECTION.
THAT WHITE HOUSE REVIEWED MORE
REGULATIONS IN HALF THE AMOUNT
OF TIME.
THE AVERAGE REVIEW TIME FOR
ECONOMIC SIGNIFICANCE SO
100 MILLION PLUS ROLE 70 DAYS
FOR THE FIRST 10 MONTHS.
OVER 100 RULES THAT HAVE BEEN
AT THE WHITE HOUSE LONGER THAN
NIBILITY DAYS WHICH IS A LONG
TIME CONSIDERING THAT MOST
SPEND 30 TO 60 DAYS THERE.
THERE IS A LOT BUILT UP AT THE
WHITE HOUSE RIGHT NOW.
>> YOU ARE SAYING WE KNOW AS
WE REPORTED THAT THE FEDERAL
AGENCIES HAVEN'T REPORTED AS
THEY ARE REQUIRED TO IN APRIL
AND OCTOBER BY CONGRESS ABOUT
THESE.
WE KNOW THERE IS A BACKLOG AT
THE WHITE HOUSE.
I FOUND SOMETHING INTERESTING
BASED ON EVERYTHING GOING ON
RIGHT NOW REGULATORY CLIFF.
SOMETHING SIGNIFICANT PEOPLE
NEED TO BE WATCHING.
>> SURE, SENATOR HAD OP. ED
ABOUT THIS REGULATORY CLIFF.
WE COUNTED UP ALL OF THE COSTS
RULES THAT COULD COME OUT OR
THAT ARE CURRENTLY AT THE
WHITE HOUSE.
IT'S ROUGHLY $100 BILLION
WORTH OF RULES.
ECONOMIC SIGNIFICANT RULES FOR
ENERGY EFFICIENCY STANDARDS
DEPARTMENT OF LABOR RULES.
THERE IS A LOT AT THE WHITE
HOUSE RIGHT NOW.
I DON'T THINK THERE WILL BE A
HUGE AVALANCHE OF RULES THEY
CAN TAKE THEIR TIME AND GET
EVERYONE IS HOPING AT LEAST
INPUT FROM BUSINESSES AND
GROUPS TO MAKE THESE RULES.
AT LEAST THE LEAST COSTLY
RULES THAT ACHIEVE THE MOST
BENEFITS OR RE-EXAMINE THE
RULES ALL TOGETHER.
>> Shannon: WE HAVE COVERED A
LOT OF THINGS.
E.P.A. RULES THAT INFRINGE ON
PEOPLE'S PRIVATE PROPERTY.
OF COURSE, THE MANDATE ABOUT
CONTRACEPTION BEING MANDATED
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
IMPACT BUSINESSES PROPERTY
PROPERTY OWNERS.
YOU ALL TRACK A NUMBER OF
THOSE.
ONE CHIEF AMONG THOSE IS THE
NEW HEALTHCARE LAW.
ALL RULES AND HASN'T GONE INTO
EFFECT YET.
$1.1 BILLION.
AND 1.4 MILLION PAPERWORK
HOURS FOR PEOPLE TO HAVE TO
KEEP UP WITH THESE
INVESTIGATIONS WHERE DOES THAT
COST FILTER TO SOMEWHERE IT
ABSORBED.
>> 1.1 FIGURES FOR THE VENDING
MACHINES AND RESTAURANTS AND
EXPANDED TO GROCERY STORES.
THE TOTAL COST IS ROUGHLY
$30 BILLION.
10.
>> ALL OF THE AFFORDABLE CARE
ACT.
CORRECT.
ONE WAY TO TAKE THESE
PAPERWORK HOURS IS TO SEE AN
AVERAGE WORK YEAR OF ROUGHLY
2,000 HOURS AND YOU ARE
TALKING ABOUT TENS OF
THOUSANDS OF EMPLOYEE YEARS
THAT WOULD TAKE JUST TO FILE
ALL THE NEW PAPERWORK THAT THE
HEALTHCARE LAW REQUIRES THERE
IS A LOT MORE TO COME IN 2013,
2014 AS WELL.
>> WHAT DO BUSINESS OWNERS DO
WITH THAT COST?
>> THEY CAN EITHER
REDISTRIBUTE LABOR TO
REGULATORY COMPLIANCE WHICH IS
SOMETHING I DON'T THINK
EVERYONE WANT IT COULD.
FORCED TO HIRE NEW PEOPLE.
YOU HAVE TO EXAMINE FOR SMALL
BUSINESSES THAT IMPACT IS MUCH
GREATER.
WE LOOKED AT A FEW LAWS UNDER
DODD FRANK A FEW REGULATIONS
WE SAW 4,000 PLUS HOURS PER
ENTITY FOR A FEW OF THE BIG
REGULATIONS.
IF YOU ARE A SMALL BUSINESS
JUST A FEW PEOPLE YOU ARE
TALKING 2 TO 3 EXTRA EMPLOYEES
THAT YOU MIGHT NEED TO HIRE OR
THERE IS A LOT OF RESHUFFLING
GOING ON.
IT DOESN'T MAKE IT ANY EASIER
TO HIRE OR EXPAND.
>> Shannon: THAT'S FOR
BUSINESSES ON THE RULES THAT
ARE SETTLED OR THEY KNOW ARE
COMING.
WHAT ABOUT THIS SITUATION
WHERE WE DO HAVE SOME OF THESE
THINGS THAT ARE LOG JAM AND
NOT COMING OUT OR LANGUISHING
BEFORE THE PUBLIC IS GETTING A
CHANCE TO COMMENT ON THEM AND
SEE HOW THEY ARE GOING TO
WORK.
WHAT DOES THAT UNCERTAINTY DO
FOR U.S. CITIZENS.
>> BLIND UNLESS YOU AREN
THIEWS AS STICK AND CHECK THE
WHITE HOUSE WEB SITE TO SEE
WHAT'S PENDING YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S GOING TO COME OUT UNDER
2013-2014.
WE DON'T HAVE A JUNE FIND
AGENDAS.
BUSINESSES DON'T KNOW WHAT'S
COMING IN 2013-2014.
ADD THE ARE A GLA TORE CLIFF
WITH THE FISCAL CLIFF IT'S
MADDENING.
PEOPLE AT LEAST WISH THEY KNEW
WHAT TO EXPECT OUT OF
WASHINGTON THE NEXT FEW YEARS
AND THEY CAN'T EVEN EXPECT
THAT.
>> Shannon: THERE IS A LOT OF
UNCERTAINTY HERE.
VERY INTERESTING HOW YOU KEEP
AN EYE ON THESE THINGS.
WE WOULD LOVE TO YOU HAVE COME
BACK.
>> THANKS SO MUCH.
>> Shannon: AS THE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION REOPENS THE
PIPELINE.
ONE SENATOR IS REMINDING THE
PRESIDENT HE NEEDS TO MAKE
THOSE INTENTIONS PUBLIC.
ROB PORTMAN SENT MR. OBAMA A
LETTER LAST WEEK REMINDING THE
WHITE HOUSE OF ITS LEGAL
REQUIREMENT TO PUBLISH THESE
REGULATORY PRESIDENT OBAMA
PROMISED THE MOST TRANSPARENT
IN HISTORY BUT HE HAS FAILED
TO COMPLY WITH THE BASIC DUTY
TO PUBLISH HIS PLANS FOR NEW
REGULATIONS AS REQUIRED BY
FEDERAL LAW.
WE WILL KEEP AN EYE ON IT.
>> Shannon: THIS SOME BREAKING
NEWS JUST IN FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
FOX NEWS HAS SPOKEN WITH
LT. PAUL VANCE WHO SAYS THERE
HAS BEEN A THREAT OF VIOLENCE
AT SAINT ROSA LIMA CHURCH.
NOW OUR REPORTER ANNA KOOIMAN
HAS BEEN THERE TODAY COVERING
THE MANY FAMILIES WHO HAVE
BEEN COMING AND GOING.
YOU HAVE SEEN THERE ARE MANY
FOLKS THERE FOR COMFORT AND
THERE FOR MASS TODAY.
THE CHURCH CHOSE TO EVACUATE.
STATE POLICE AND NEWTOWN
POLICE SEARCHED THE CHURCH.
THERE WAS SOME TYPE OF THREAT
BUT SAID THEY FOUND NOTHING.
THE CHURCH IS CLEAR NOW.
FOLKS HAVE BEEN CLEARED TO GO
BACK IN AND SERVICES THERE
CONTINUE.
POLICE ARE NOT BEING SPECIFIC
ABOUT WHAT TYPE OF THREAT
THERE WAS.
BUT, AGAIN, MANY OF THE FAMILY
AND FRIENDS OF THOSE GRIEVING
OVER THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SHOOTING HAVE BEEN TAKING PART
IN SERVICES THERE THIS
MORNING.
WE WILL KEEP YOU UPDATED AS WE
KNOW MORE.
THE SHOOTING IN NEW TOWN IT,
CONNECTICUT HAS THE COUNTRY
GRIEVIHIS MORNING ON
THE SUNDAY TALK SHOW WE SAW
PUSH FOR ACTION TO PREVENT
MASS MURDERS FROM OCCURRING.
STAY WITH US.
WE WILL TELL WHAT YOU
LAWMAKERS IN WASHINGTON ARE
PROPOSING, WHAT THEY HAVE HAD
TO SAY ABOUT THE TRAGEDY AND
HOW THEY HOPE TO STOP
SOMETHING SIMILAR FROM
HAPPENING EVER AGAIN.
AND, ALSO --
I HAD ENOUGH OF FEELING
EMBARRASSED ABOUT MY SKIN.
[ Designer ]
ENOUGH OF JUST COVERING UP
MY MODERATE TO SEVERE
I DECI      ♪
[ Spa Lady ]
I STARTED ENBREL.
IT'S CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO PROVIDE CLEARER SKIN.
[ RV Guy ] ENBREL MAY NOT WORK
FOR EVERYONE --
AND MAY NOT CLEAR YOU
COMPLETELY,
BUT FOR MANY, IT GETS SKIN
CLEARER FAST, WITHIN 2 MONTHS,
AND KEEPS IT CLEARER
UP TO 9 MONTHS.
[ Male Announcer ]
BECAUSE ENBREL®, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL,
EVENTS INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS, LYMPHOMA,
OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING ENBREL,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START ENBREL IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON ENBREL, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING,
OR PALENESS.
IF YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH, ASK
YOUR DERMATOLOGIST ABOUT ENBREL.
I HAVE A COLD,
AND I TOOK NYQUIL,
BUT I'M STILL "STUBBED" UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT DOESN'T HAVE A DECONGESTANT.
NO WAY.
[ Male Announcer ] SORRY.
Alka-Seltzer Plus FIGHTS
YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A FAST ACTING
DECONGESTANT
TO RELIEVE YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
[ sighs ] THANKS!
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus.
♪ OH
WHAT A RELIEF IT IS! ♪
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
AND SAVE $1
VISIT Alka-Seltzer ON FACEBOOK.
MAKE A WISH!
I WISH WE COULD
LIE HERE FOREVER.
I WISH THIS TEST DRIVE WAS OVER,
SO WE COULD HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
TEST DRIVE!
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A JETTA.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN,
$0 DUE AT SIGNING, $0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
>> Shannon: PRESIDENT OBAMA
WILL SPEND THE AFTERNOON
VISITING PRIVATELY WITH
FAMILIES OF THOSE WHO LOST
LOVED ONES IN CONNECTICUT.
THE PRESIDENT WILL LEAVE
WASHINGTON IN ABOUT AN HOUR
AND WILL SPEAK AT THE NEWTOWN
HIGH SCHOOL AT 7:00 EASTERN
TONIGHT.
EARLIER THIS MORNING.
MR. OBAMA TOOK THE CHANCE TO
SPEND TIME WITH HIS OWN
DAUGHTER AT HER DANCE
REHEARSAL.
BRET BAIER WILL HAVE LIVE
COVERAGE OF THE PRESIDENT'S
VISIT RIGHT HERE ON FOX NEWS
TONIGHT.
THAT STARTS AT 6:00 P.M.
EASTERN.
VOTERS' RIGHTS GROUPS IN EGYPT
ARE CALLING FOUL ON
CONSTITUTIONAL DRAFT SAYING
YESTERDAY'S REFERENDUM VOTE
WAS MARRED BY VIOLATIONS.
THEY CLAIM THERE WASN'T ENOUGH
JUDICIAL OVERSIGHT AND WOMEN
WERE VOTED FROM VOTING AT ALL.
MEANWHILE THE MUSLIM
BROTHERHOOD IS CLAIMING EARLY
VICTORY ON ISLAMIC BACKED
RESOLUTION.
SENATOR JOHN KERRY IS EXPECTED
TO BE NOMINATED THE NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE.
INITIAL ANNOUNCEMENT COULD
COME EARLY NEXT WEEK PRESIDENT
OBAMA HAS NOT FINALIZED HIS
PICKS FOR THE REST OF THE
NATIONAL SECURITY TEAM
CHURCHES IN NEWTOWN HAVE
BECOME SOLACE.
SAINT LIMA CHURCH CONSOLING
SEVERAL VICTIMS OF THE
VICTIMS.
ANNA KOOIMAN LIVE AT THE
CHURCH WHERE THE PEOPLE HAVE
BEEN FILING IN AND OUT OF
MASS.
HELLO, ANNA.
YOU CAME IN WITH AN ALERT ON
THIS WE DID HAVE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE AND NEWTOWN
POLICE STILL ON THE SCENE.
THE CHURCH WAS EVACUATED BUT
THE SERVICE WAS ALREADY
WRAPPING UP.
WE DID SPEAK WITH LT. ADVANCE
TALKING TO FOX NEWS SAYING
THERE WAS SOME SORT OF
VIOLENCE DID NOT MENTION
SPECIFICALLY WHAT SORT IT WAS
BUT THAT IT IS CLEAR AND
PEOPLE ARE ALLOWED TO GO BACK
INTO THE CHURCH BUT, OF
COURSE, IT'S HAPPENING AS THE
ENTIRE NATION IS SEARCHING FOR
A SAVING GRACE.
MANY PEOPLE CHOOSING TO GO TO
SUNDAY MORNING SERVICES LIKE
THE ONE THAT JUST WRAPPED UP
BEHIND ME.
FEELING DEFLATED AND HOPELESS
AND THIS COMING AS THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER IS RELEASING THE
IDENTITIES OF THE 12 LITTLE
GIRLS, 8 IN THE BOYS AND THE
SIX ADULTS WHO LOST THEIR
LIVES IN THE FRIDAY MORNING
MASSACRE.
IN THE HALLWAY AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST WAS
FOUND ALONG WITH THE
47-YEAR-OLD PRINCIPAL DAN HOW
HOCHSPRUNG.
>> SHE WAS PERSONAL FRIEND AND
WONDERFUL LEADER AND IT'S A
HUGE LOSS FOR THE KIDS AND THE
COMMUNITY AND HER FAMILY.
>> WHILE SOME FOLKS IN THE
AREA TOOK DOWN HOLIDAY
CELEBRATIONS FEELING GUILTY
CELEBRATING DURING THIS TIME
OF TRAGEDY.
OTHERS ARE FINDING A NEW
MEANING ASSOCIATED WITH ANGELS
BEING PLACED ON TOP CHRISTMAS
TREES.
SHERRI BURTON SAYS IT PAYS
TRIBUTE TO THE STUDENT AND
STAFF MEMBERS SHE LOVED SO
MUCH.
>> WE WILL GET THROUGH THIS I
HAVE LOST FRIENDS AND STUDENTS
I HAVE WORKED WITH.
>> SOME OF THE PARENTS WHO
LOST THEIR CHILDREN MOURNING
WITH THEIR FELLOW NEIGHBORS
THIS MORNING DURING PACKED
SUNDAY SERVICES DISHEARTENED
PARENTS WHO ARE TAKING A BREAK
FROM PLANNING FUNERALS FOR
THEIR LITTLE ONES.
MANY RESIDENTS FEEL THEY HAVE
NO WAY TO HELP THE VICTIM'S
FAMILIES EXCEPT THROUGH FAITH
AND PRAYER.
SHANNON, AS WE HAVE BEEN
MENTIONING ALL MORNING LONG, OBS
SCHEDULED TO COME TO SANDY
HOOK.
THIS IS THE FOURTH TIME THAT
HE HAS GONE TO TOWNS THAT ARE
IN MOURNING FOLLOWING MASS
SHOOTINGS.
BACK TO YOU.
>> ANNA, THANK YOU VERY MUCH
FOR KEEPING US UPDATED.
WE ARE SLOWLY LEARNING MORE
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED IN SHOOK
SANDY HOOK OLMERT TRI.
>> THERE NEEDS TO BE
CONVERSATION ABOUT GUN CONTROL
BUT ALSO THE WAY WE TREAT
MENTAL ILLNESS.
ALSO ABOUT THE CULTURE OF
VIOLENCE IN THIS COUNTRY WHICH
MAY HAVE CONTRIBUTE TO THE WAY
IN WHICH THIS VERY DISTURBED
YOUNG MAN THOUGHT.
>> OBVIOUSLY PART OF A
DIFFERENT CONVERSATION.
LET'S CHECK IN WITH STEVE
CENTANNI WHO HAS BEEN
MONITORING WHAT'S GOING ON
HERE IN WASHINGTON IN REACTION
TO THE SHOOTING.
STEVE?
>> YEAH, SHANNON, REACTION
HERE IN WASHINGTON.
SO FAR VERY FAR REACHING SHOCK
AND GRIEF NEW PUSH FOR GUN
CONTROL AS YOU CAN IMAGINE AND
IDEAS FOR DEALING WITH MASS
VIOLENCE IN THIS COUNTRY.
EVERYONE SEEMS TO AGREE IT'S A
DIFFICULT CHALLENGE WITH NO
EYESY SOLUTIONS.
>> WE HAVE TO COME A KNOWLEDGE
THERE IS NO SIMPLE SOLUTION.
YES THERE NEEDS TO BE A
CONVERSATION ABOUT GUN CONTROL
BUT ALSO ABOUT THE WAY WE
TREAT MENTAL ILLNESS, ALSO
ABOUT THE CULTURE OF VIOLENCE
IN THIS COUNTRY WHICH MAY HAVE
CONTRIBUTED TO THE WAY IN
WHICH THIS VERY DISTURBED
YOUNG MAN THOUGHT OF COURSE A
HOT TOPIC ON THE SUNDAY TALK
SHOWS.
JOE LIEBERMAN OF CONNECTICUT
AND CONGRESSMAN JASON CHAFFETS
OF UTAH BOTH SUGGESTING THE
MATS MEDIA INCLUDING VIOLENT
NEGATIVE VIDEO GAMES
NEGATIVELY INFLUENCE
IMPRESSIONABLE YOUNG MEN.
DICK DURBIN AND LIEBERMAN
SUGGESTING A NATIONAL
COMMISSION ON MASS VIOLENCE TO
FIND WAYS OF PREVENTING FUTURE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS.
AND SOME ARE POINTING TO A
BETTER MENTAL HEALTH AND
BETTER MENTAL HEALTH SCREENING
AS PART OF THE ANSWER.
>> I THINK WE HAVE TO BE
CAREFUL ABOUT SUGGESTING NEW
GUN LAWS.
WE NEED TO LOOK AT WHAT DRIVES
A CRAZY PERSON TO DO THESE
KIND OF ACTIONS.
MAKE SURE THAT WE ARE
ENFORCING THE LAWS THAT ARE
CURRENTLY ON THE BOOKS.
>> OF COURSE, PRESIDENT OBAMA
LEAVING THE WHITE HOUSE THIS
AFTERNOON FOR A VIGIL AT THE
HIGH SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
MASSACHUSETTS.
SHANNON?
>> Shannon: STEVE, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
I THINK WE NEED A NATIONAL
COMMISSION ON MASS VIOLENCE.
NOT TO -- IN PLACE OF ANYTHING
ELSE THE CONGRESS OR STATE
GOVERNMENTS MIGHT WANT TO DO
BUT TO MAKE SURE THAT THE
HEART BREAK AND ANGER THAT WE
FEEL NOW IS NOT DISSIPATED
OVER TIME OR LOST IN
LEGISLATIVE GRIDLOCK.
>>
>> Shannon: THAT WAS SENATOR
LIEBERMAN ON "FOX NEWS SUNDAY"
SAYING IT IS TIME FOR
WASHINGTON TO FORM A NATIONAL
COMMISSION TO STUDY MASS
VIOLENCE IN OUR COUNTRY.
EARLIER TODAY I SAT DOWN WITH
ANCHOR CHRIS WALLACE TO GET
HIS PREVIEW OF THIS WEEK'S
SHOW.
CHRIS, IT'S A TOUGH STORY ALL
THE WAY AROUND.
YOU HAD SENATOR LIEBERMAN OF
COURSE HOME STATE ON "FOX NEWS
SUNDAY" TO TALK WITH YOU
TODAY.
>> Chris: RIGHT, SENATOR FOR
24 YEARS.
EFFORTS TOWN ME ABOUT THIS
TOWN OF NEWTOWN.
OF COURSE HE KNOWS THE WHOLE
STATE SO WELL.
HE SAID THIS THE QUITEST MOST
INNOCENT TOWN IN THE WORLD.
IT'S THE LAST PLACE.
IT ISN'T THE LAST PLACE.
BECAUSE IT CAN HAPPEN
EVERYWHERE AND ANYWHERE FOUR
COUNTRY.
PEOPLE WE HAVE A NUMBER OF TWO
SENATORS AND A CONGRESSMAN AND
SCHOOL SAFETY EXPERT THEY ARE
FLOUNDERING AROUND TRYING TO
FIND ANSWER AND LIEBERMAN
CALLS FOR NATIONAL COMMISSION
AND DURBIN, SENATOR DURBIN
CALLS FOR HEARINGS AND THERE
IS TALK ABOUT, YOU KNOW, GUN
CONTROL.
AND THEN THERE IS TALK ABOUT,
YOU KNOW, TRYING TO DO
SOMETHING TO PROTECT OUR
SCHOOLS.
AND LOUIE GOHMERT A
CONGRESSMAN FROM TEXAS TALKS
ABOUT ALLOWING PEOPLE TO HAVE
MORE GUNS SO PEOPLE CAN STAND
UP IN A PLUCK PLACE AND DEFEND
THEMSELVES.
YOU KNOW IT'S THE WORST CASE
WE CAN IMAGINE AND I DON'T
KNOW IF YOU CAN ANSWER.
>> YOU WERE ABLE TO TALK TO
SOME OF THE FAMILIES AS WELL.
FOR THEM VERY MIXED EMOTIONS.
THEIR FRIENDS' CHILDREN ARE
OKAY BUT THEIR FRIEND'S
CHILDREN ARE NOT OKAY.
>> THE ONE FAMILY IN
PARTICULAR LICOTAS DESCRIBED
IT BITTERSWEET.
THIS LITTLE BOY ADEN WAS IN
THE FIRST GRADE CLASSROOM WITH
THAT WONDERFUL TEACHER
VICTORIA SOTO 27 YEARS OLD.
COME AND BURSTS IN.
SHE JUMPS UP TO CONFRONT HIM
TO TRY TO PROTECT HER
CHILDREN.
HE SHOOTS HER IN FRONT OF THE
AND LITTLE ADEN TAKES THAT
SECOND TO RUN OUT OF THE
CLASSROOM BUT ALSO TO GET SOME
OF HIS FRIENDS.
HE DIDN'T GO OUT BY HIMSELF.
GRABBED SOME OF HIS FRIENDS,
RAN OUT.
THEY WERE SAFE.
SHE DIED.
SOME OF THEIR CLASSMATES DIED
AS ROBERT LICOTO'S DAD SAID HE
ALSO HAD AN OLDER DAUGHTER IN
THE SCHOOL.
WE ARE LUCKY AND FORTUNATE.
I CAN'T TAKE ANY JOY IN IT
OBVIOUSLY AS RELIEVED AS THEY
ARE BECAUSE SO MANY OF OUR
FRIENDS AND SOME OF THE KIDS
ARE GONE.
>> Shannon: YOU TALK ABOUT
THOSE SPECIAL MOMENTS AND
PEOPLE LIKE THAT YOUNG TEACHER
WHO ARE A HERO AND I THOUGHT
IT WAS VERY FITTING THAT "FOX
NEWS SUNDAY" WRAPS UP WITH
SOME OF THE BEST MOMENTS AND
THE PEOPLE WHO TRULY ARE THE
HEROS.
>> Chris: THERE IS GOOD AND
STRENGTH AND IN THE FACE OF
THESE.
>> Shannon: THANK YOU.
YOU CATCHALL OF "FOX NEWS
SUNDAY" RIGHT HERE ON THE FOX
NEWS CHANNEL AIRING RIGHT
AFTER AMERICA'S NEWS
HEADQUARTERS.
>> 6-YEAR-OLD NOAH IS ONE OF
THE CHILDREN WHOSE LIFE WAS
CUT SHORT LAST FRIDAY.
ACCORDING TO HIS UNCLE HE WAS
SMART AS A WHIP.
WHEN HIS MOTHER TOLD HIM SHE
LOVED HIM, HE WOULD SAY NOT AS
MUCH AS I LOVE YOU, MOM.
HE CALLED HIS TWIN SISTER
AERIAL BEST FRIEND AND ALSO
INSEPARABLE FROM 8-YEAR-OLD
SISTER SOPHIE.
NEITHER OF HIS SISTERS WERE
INJURED IN THE SHOOTING.
HIS FUNERAL IS PLANNED FOR
TOMORROW.
SINCE AUTHORITIES RELEASED THE
NAMES OF ALL THOSE WHO DIED AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
WE HAVE BEEN LEARNING MORE
ABOUT THEM.
GO TO FOX NEWS TO THE COME TO
READ ALL OF THEIR VERY
PERSONAL STORIES.
AMONG THOSE OFFERING HELP IN
THE AFTERMATH OF THIS TRAGEDY
REVEREND BILLY GRAHAM'S RAPID
RESPONSE TEAM.
WE WILL TALK TO ONE OF
MINISTERS NEXT.
FIRST A POWERFUL IMAGE THE
LIST AND NAMES OF THE TENDER
AGES OF THE VICTIMS OF THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SHOOTING.
[ Mother ]
YOU CAN'T LEAVE THE TABLE
TILL YOU FINISH YOUR VEGETABLES.
[ clock ticking ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THERE'S A BETTER WAY...
V8 V-FUSION.
VEGETABLE NUTRITION THEY NEED,
FRUIT TASTE THEY LOVE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
OR...TRY KIDS BOXES!
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFTS TO CLEAR OBSTACLES.
♪
LOWERS TO CUT DRAG.
RISES TO EVERY CHALLENGE.
THE CLASS EXCLUSIVE
AIR SUSPENSION
IN THE NEW 2013 RAM 1500.
ENGINEERED TO MOVE HEAVEN
AND EARTH.
GUTS. GLORY.
RAM.
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAN
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
>> Shannon: AMONG THOSE
FLOODING INTO NEW TOWN
CONNECTICUT TO OFFER COMFORT
AND SUPPORT.
MEMBERS OF THE BILLY GRAHAM
RAPID RESPONSE TEAM THE
MINISTRY SENT IN A TEAM OF 10
MINISTERS CLAIMED THANK YOU SO
MUCH FOR YOUR TIME.
CAN YOU TELL US WHAT YOU FOUND
WHEN YOU ARRIVED THERE?
>> YES, WHEN EARRIVED ACTUALLY
THE DAY OF THE SHOOTING WITH
OUR SHAP PLANS, WE FOUND AN
INCREDIBLE COMMUNITY OF
SUFFERING, THE AGONY THIS WAS
THERE, THE SHOCK THAT WAS
THERE.
AND AS WE DO WHEN WE GO TO
DISASTERS LIKE, THIS WE FIRST
CHECK WITH THE AUTHORITIES IN
THE AREA.
THE STATE POLICE AND THE FIRE
FOLKS THAT WERE HERE TO LET
THEM KNOW THEY WERE HERE AND
ASK HOW WE CAN SERVE THEM.
>> AND HOW DO YOU EVEN BEGIN
TO TALK TO THESE FAMILIES,
WHETHER THEY WERE DIRECTLY
IMPACTED OR MEMBERS OF THIS
COMMUNITY ALL FEELING THE
GRIEF AT THIS POINT HOW DO YOU
TALK THEM THROUGH WHERE THEY
ARE RIGHT NOW?
>> WELL, IN A TIME LIKE, THIS
IT'S REALLY MORE ABOUT
LISTENING IT'S HELPING PEOPLE
TO EXPRESS THEMSELF.
MUCH OF OUR WORK AT THIS POINT
HAS BEEN WITH THE FIRST
RESPONDERS THE THAN PLANS THAT
WE BROUGHT IN ARE ALSO FIRST
RESPONDERS AS WELL.
POLICE CHAPLAINS, RETIRED FIRE
CHAPLAINS AND THEY JUST COME
ALONGSIDE WHAT WE WOULD CALL A
MINISTRY OF PRESENCE TO LET
THEM KNOW THAT WE ARE HERE
MAKE OUR SSTLESZ AVAILABLE TO
THEM.
AND MANY INVOLVED AT THE SCENE
REALLY TOOK OOUR CHAPLAINS AND
TALKED TO THEM ON A ONE-ON-ONE
BASIS.
>> I WOULD IMAGINE ALONG WITH
FAMILIES WHO HAVE LOST WHETHER
IT'S CHILDREN OR ON ADULT
LOVED ONE THE FIRST RESPONDERS
AND THE PEOPLE WHO HAVE TO BE
THERE AND WORK THROUGH SEEING
THE SCENE AND HANDLING THE
AFTERMATH, I WOULD IMAGINE
THOSE ARE.  SO FOLKS THAT MOST
NEED SOME HELP, WHETHER AS YOU
SAID IT'S JUST LISTENING AT
THIS POINT.
>>.
>> YOU ARE RIGHT.
WHAT WE ARE HEARING IS JUST
HORRIFIC.
THERE AREN'T WORDS TO DESCRIBE
THE SCENE OUR HEART JUST GOES
OUT TO THE FAMILIES.
WE ARE -- OUR ENTIRE
ORGANIZATION OF GLOBALLY IS
PRAYING AS WE KNOW.
PEOPLE ARE JUST THROUGH THE
THIS REGION.
WHEN WE ARE THERE THE ONLY
HOPE PEOPLE CAN HAVE IS TO THE
LORD.
MUCH OF WHAT WE HAVE BEEN
HEARING ON TV, CENTERS AROUND
FAITH.
AND WE RECOGNIZE THAT THIS IS
A CRITICAL TIME FOR EVERYONE
TO REALLY TAP IN ON WHAT GOD'S
COMFORT AND HOPE IS ALL ABOUT.
>> Shannon: FOR A LOT OF
PEOPLE WHO MAYBE FAITH FOR
THEM ISN'T A DAILY PART OF
THEIR LIFE.
MAYBE IT WAS AT ONE POINT.
MAYBE IT'S SOMETHING NEW FOR
THEM.
WHY DO YOU THINK IN TIME OF
CRISIS WE ARE SO QUICK TO TURN
TO THAT PLACE?
>> WELL, WE GO THROUGH TIMES
LIKE, THIS YOU KNOW.
WE REALLY COME IN TOUCH WITH
THE IMPORTANT THINGS OF LIFE.
AND I THINK A RELATIONSHIP
EXPERIENCING GOD'S COMFORT AND
HIS HOPE IS WHAT PEOPLE SEEK.
WHETHER ANYONE HAS BEEN IN
CHURCH IN THE LAST 10 YEARS OR
NOT, THERE IS SOMETHING I
THINK THAT'S IN THEIR HEART
THEY REALIZE THERE IS A HOLE
THERE.
AND THEY TURN TO GOD.
AND THEY ASK US A LOT OF GOD
QUESTIONS.
WE DON'T PRETEND TO HAVE ALL
THE ANSWERS.
WE KNOW DOO KNOW THERE IS A
GOD THAT LOVES THEM AND CARES
FOR THEM AND DESIRES TO COME
ALONGSIDE AT A TIME THAT COULD
BE THE DARKEST HOUR OF THEIR
LIFE.
>> JACK MONDAY WE THANK YOU
YOU AND YOUR TEAM TO LISTEN
AND BE A PRESENCE FOR THOSE IN
NEED.
FOLKS WANT TO KNOW MORE IT'S
BILLY GRAHAM.ORG SLASH RRT FOR
RAPID RESPONSE TEAM WE THANK
YOU FOR YOUR WORK THERE, SIR.
>> THANK YOU.
>> IN ABOUT AN HOUR, PRESIDENT
OBAMA IS GOING TO LEAVE
WASHINGTON AND HEAD TO NEW
TOWN CONNECTICUT.
HE IS FLYING THERE TO MEET
WITH VICTIM'S FAMILY MEMBERS
AND FIRST RESPONDERS.
LATER THIS EVENING HE WILL
SPEAK AT A PRAYER VIGIL.
BRET BAIER WILL ANCHOR LIVE
COVERAGE OF THE PRESIDENT'S
VISIT.
IT BEGINS AT 6:00 EASTERN.
>> AND SWITCHING GEARS.
AS WE ALL KNOW THE HOLIDAY
SEASON IS UPON US.
SO HOW ARE THINGS LOOKING FOR
SMALL BUSINESSES?
ACCORDING TO A NEW SURVEY, NOT
ALL THAT GREAT.
SENIOR BUSINESS CORRESPONDENT
BRENDA BUTTNER WILL TELL IT US
MORE.
WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>> TOUCH THEIR HEARTS.
EASE THEIR PAIN DURING THIS
SEASON MORE FERVENTLY TO
PRAYER AND TO -- THOSE
AFFECTED BY THIS TRAGEDY,
BLESSINGS.
>> Shannon: POPE BENEDICT
OFFERING PRAYERS TO EVERYONE
WHO LOST LOVED ONES ON FRIDAY
IN CONNECTICUT.
THE PONTIFF SAYS HE WAS DEEPLY
SADDENED BY THE SHOOTING AND
ALSO GRIEVING WITH THE
FAMILIES.
♪ NOW TO SOME HOLIDAY SHOPPING
LESS THAN ENCOURAGING NEWS
FROM SMALL BUSINESS OWNERS,
BRENDA BUTLER JOINS US LIVE
WITH A SURVEY TAKEN TELLS US
NEW INFORMATION.
HELLO, BRENDA.
>> HEY, SHANNON GLASS HALF
FULL OR EMPTY.
BUSINESS OWNERS EMPTY IS THE
EARN AS ARE THEIR BUCKET FOR
SPENDING.
NET CAPITAL SPENDING NEXT 12
MONTHS DRAMATICALLY DROPPED TO
THE LOWEST LEVEL IN MORE THAN
2 YEARS.
THAT'S THE WORD FROM THE WELLS
FARGO.
IT MAY MEAN OWNERS MAY PULL
BACK ON INVESTMENTS EVEN MORE.
>> OVERALL OPTIMISM AMONG THE
SMALL GUYS ON MAIN STREET
OWNERS ARE DRAMATICALLY MORE
PESSIMISTIC.
ANOTHER KEY SURVEY SHOWS
NEARLY 50% OF SMALL BUSINESS
OWNERS EXPECTING THINGS TO GET
WORSE OVER THE NEXT SIX
MONTHS.
THE OPTIMISM INDEX NATIONAL
FEDERATION OF BUSINESS DROPPED
TO LOWEST LEVEL OF INDEX'S 26
YEAR LOW HISTORY.
ONLY LOWER IN THE 2008
MELTDOWN AND FALLOUT.
SUPER STORM SANDY DOESN'T GET
MUCH OF THE BLAME.
STORMS HARD HIT WEREN'T
CLIEWTTLEDDED IN THE MATH.
THE REASON FOR THE MAUL
BUSINESS GLOOM YOU GUESSED IT
WORRIES ABOUT THE ECONOMY.
ESPECIALLY EXPECTATIONS FOR
NEXT YEAR.
THE NFIB CHIEF'S ECONOMIST
SAYS THE ELECTION JUST DIDN'T
GIVE THOSE SURVEYED ANY REASON
TO HOPE THINGS MIGHT GET
BETTER.
>> WE WOKE UP AFTER SPENDING
BILLIONS ON THE ELECTION AND
EVERYTHING WAS THE SAME.
AND SINCE THEY WERE UNABLE TO
REALLY KIND OF COME UP WITH A
SCHEME FOR US BEFORE, I GUESS
OWNERS ARE NOW PRETTY
PESSIMISTIC THAT THEY WILL BE
ABLE TO DO IT NOW.
>> SMALL BUSINESS WHICH
LARGELY DRIVES HIRING IS
PESSIMISTIC, THAT COULD BE A
SELF-FULFILLING PROPHECY.
>> WITH THAT KIND OF OUTLOOK
ON THE ECONOMY.
YOU ARE NOT GOING TO HIRE OR
MAKE CAPITAL SPENDING OR DO
ANY OF THESE THINGS THAT WOULD
HELP GROW G.D.P. AND BOOST THE
UNEMPLOYMENT RATE.
>> IT'S NOT JUST FIRMS BUT
THEIR CUSTOMERS AS WELL.
INDEX OF CONSUMER CONFIDENCE
BY THE UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN
SHOWS THAT CONSUMERS ARE ALSO
VERY PESSIMISTIC.
BACK TO YOU, SHANNON.
>> ALL RIGHT, BRENDA, THANK
YOU FOR KEEPING US UPDATED AS
THOUGH MOURN THE SCHOOL MATES
THEY LOST THEY WILL NOT HAVE
TO RETURN WHEN SCHOOL REOPENS
THIS WEEK.
WE WILL TELL YOU ABOUT OTHER
PLANS FOR THEM NEXT.
[ Woman ] Ring. Ring.
Progresso.
Your soups are
so awesomely delicious
my husband and I
can't stop eating 'em!
What's...that...
on your head?
Can curlers!
Tomato Basil,
Potato with bacon...
we've got a lot of empty cans.
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
we've got a lot of empty cans.
WHY LET CONSTIPATION
STRY MIRALAX.?
MIRLAX WORKSDIFFERENTLY THAN
OTHER LAXATIVES.
IT DWS WATER INTO YOUR COLON
TO UNBLOCK YOUR
SYSTEM NATURALLY.
DON'T WAIT TO FE GREAT.
MIRALAX.
>> AS YOU KNOW AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY ON FRIDAY THERE
WERE 26 VICTIMS SHOT DEAD.
20 CHILDREN, SIX ADULTS.
WE'RE GETTING A LOOK AT THEIR
PICTURES, PERSONAL LIVES
LEARNING MORE ABOUT THEM
TODAY.
AND WE'RE ALSO LEARNING THAT
THE CHILDREN WHO SURVIVED WILL
BE GOING BACK TO SCHOOL LATER
THIS WEEK.
NOW, THEY ARE NOT GOING TO GO
BACK TO SANDY HOOK SCHOOL,
INSTEAD WE'RE TOLD THEY ARE
GOING TO USE AN UNUSED SCHOOL
A FEW MILES A AWAY.
THE HOPES ARE TO KEEP THEM
TOGETHER.
LATEST ON THE INVESTIGATION.
CONNECTICUT POLICE SAY THEY DO
HAVE EVIDENCE IN THE CASE AND
THAT THEY ARE TRACING ALL THE
WEAPONS BACK TO THE ACTUAL
WORK BENCHES WHERE THEY WERE
MADE THINK WANT TO KNOW
EVERYBODY ABOUT THEM.
THEY ARE WARNING PEOPLE TO
QUIT USING SOCIAL MEDIA TO
QUIT SPREADING MISINFORMATION.
WE HAVE BEEN ASKING YOU WHAT
YOU THINK ABOUT SPEAKER
BOEHNER'S PROPOSAL TO INCREASE
TAXES ON THOSE WHO MAKE MORE
THAN A MILLION DOLLARS A YEAR