>>> AN EXCITING MEDICAL BREAK
THROUGH GIVING PEOPLE NEW HOPE,
THOSE THAT SUFFER SPINAL CORD
INJURIES HOPE TO FINALLY WALK
AGAIN.
>> NOW THAT I'M ON MY FEET, I
FEEL NORMAL AGAIN.
IT'S LIKE IT DIDN'T HAPPEN,
WHICH IS HOW I SEE IT.
SINCE AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL
WAS FOUNDED BACK IN 1894,
THEY'VE BEEN COMMITTED
TO PUTTING CLIENTS FIRST.
HELPING GENERATIONS
THROUGH TOUGH TIMES.
GOOD TIMES.
NEVER TAKING A BAILOUT.
THERE WHEN YOU NEED THEM.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
OVER THE CENTURIES.
THE STRENGTH OF
A GLOBAL FINANCIAL LEADER.
THE HEART OF
A ONE-TO-ONE RELATIONSHIP.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
Yofor giving the perfect gift?le
just have a knack
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
They put real thought into it.
And find just...
the right...thing.
How do they do that?
More sav
That's the power of The
Home Depot.
Pick up a RIDGID JobMax
multi-tool starter kit and
get a free head attachment.
>>> ON THIS SOMBER SUNDAY IT'S
TIME AS ALWAYS FOR "SUNDAY HOUSE
CALL."
JOINING US, DR. DAVID SOMATI.
>> DR. MARC SIEGEL IS HERE,
ASSOCIATE PREFERS OF MEDICINE AT
LANGLE MEDICAL CENTER.
BOTH DOCTORS HAVE SURELY
ATTENDED TO VICTIMS IN TRAGIC
SITUATIONS SO WE WANTED TO START
THERE.
GOOD MORNING TO BOTH OF YOU.
>> GOOD MORNING.
>> WE'RE GOING TO DEDICATE MUCH
OF "SUNDAY HOUSE CALL" TO
SERIOUS HEALTH ISSUES THAT
FOLLOW THE AFTERMATH OF A
TRAGEDY LIKE SANDY HOOK WHERE ON
FRIDAY A GUNMAN KILLED 26
PEOPLE, INCLUDING 20 LITTLE
CHILDREN.
TRAUMATIC EVENTS HAVE REAL AND
LASTING EFFECTS ON A WIDE RANGE
OF PEOPLE FROM FAMILIES OF THE
VICTIMS TO THE SURVIVORS AND
THEIR FAMILIES.
ALSO THE FIRST RESPONDERS.
WE DON'T WANT TO FORGET THEM.
AND ALSO PEOPLE WATCHING THE
EVENTS ON TV.
WHAT DO YOU THINK WE NEED TO
KEEP IN MIND AT THIS TIME?
>> THE FIRST THING WE NEED TO DO
IS COME TOGETHER AS A COUNTRY.
THIS IS ANOTHER EXAMPLE OF
ANOTHER 9/11 AND IT'S 9/12.
THE ENTIRE COUNTRY GOT TOGETHER
AND UNITED AS A NATION.
THAT'S HOW WE'RE GOING TO HEAL
AND CARE FOR EACH OTHER.
LOOK, THIS IS A BIG IMPACT.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE IN
CONNECTICUT TO FEEL THIS.
I WAS WATCHING THIS YESTERDAY.
I HAVE TWO KIDS.
6-YEAR-OLD AND 10-YEAR-OLD AND
IT'S VERY EMOTIONAL.
>> WHAT ARE YOU ALLOWING THEM TO
KNOW?
>> I ONLY FEED THEM A CERTAIN
AMOUNT.
I DON'T WANT THEM TO WATCH
EVERYTHING.
I WANT THEM TO BECOME STRONGER.
I'M A SURGEON SO I DIVE RIGHT IN
AND SAID LOOK, THIS IS WHAT
HAPPENED.
WHAT IS YOUR THOUGHT?
AND MY SON ALEX TOLD ME THAT,
DAD, THAT'S WHY I'M LEARNING
KARATE.
I'M GOING TO DEFEND MYSELF AND
MY TEACHER.
MY DAUGHTER IS SAD AND SAID WHY
IS THIS HAPPENING?
THE DISCUSSION OF EVIL AND
PEOPLE SNAPPING, WHICH IS WHAT
WE HEAR ON THE MEDIA, DOESN'T
MAKE SENSE.
I DON'T THINK THEY'RE EVIL, IT'S
PSYCHOLOGICAL ISSUES AND A
COMBINATION OF FAMILY CORE,
WHETHER IT HAS TO DO WITH A MOM
TAKING HIM WITH THIS RIFLE AND
GUNS, IT'S A CULTUREAL ISSUE,
MAYBE TOO MANY VIDEO GAMES BUT
THERE'S A PSYCHOLOGICAL EFFECT.
THIS IS A FACE OF A PSYCHE.
ASPERGER'S AND AUTISM IS NOT A
PREREQUISITE TO VIOLENCE.
THEY'RE KIND, CARING, GOOD
PEOPLE IN A FAMILY THAT NURTURES
THEM.
AUTISM PLUS PSYCHOSIS CAN TURN
INTO A MONITOR.
NOBODY WILL WAKE UP AND SAY
TODAY I'M GOING TO START
SHOOTING PEOPLE.
THEY'RE AROUND US.
AS A DOCTOR, WE NEED TO DIAGNOSE
THIS FIRST BEFORE THEY GET US.
I HAVE CALLED OFF ON PEOPLE THAT
I THOUGHT LOOKED ODD.
THEY'RE USUALLY SHY.
THEY DON'T INTERACT.
THERE'S NO EYE CONTACT.
WE KNOW THEM.
IT'S NOT BULLY THEM.
WE NEED TO MAKE SURE TEACHERS
AND SOCIETY IS AWARE AND MAKE IT
THERE FOR ALL OF US.
>> TRY TO RECOGNIZE US.
BEFORE WE STARTED, THIS YOUNG
MAN WENT THROUGH THINGS THAT A
LOT OF US DO.
A DIVORCE, A BROTHER WHO DIDN'T
TALK TO HIM, A FATHER WHO WAS
ALSO NOT TALKING TO HIM.
BUT A LOT OF US EXPERIENCE THAT.
>> YOU KNOW, FIRST OF ALL, I
THINK WE NEED TO WORK ON THE
MENTAL HEALTH INFRASTRUCTURE IN
THIS COUNTRY.
WE DON'T KNOW IF THIS PERSON WAS
IN TREATMENT, IF HE WAS IN
TREATMENT, SOMEONE SHOULD LOOK
BACK AND SAID DID HE GET ENOUGH,
WAS IT EFFECTIVE.
DAVID MADE POINTS ABOUT
UNDERLYING PROBLEMS THAT MIGHT
NOT BE RELATED TO THIS.
PEOPLE NEED TO KNOW JUST BECAUSE
SOMEONE THINKS SOMETHING OUT AND
HAS A PLAN, I'M GOING TO DRIVE
TO THAT SCHOOL.
IT LOOKS COLD AND CALCULATED BUT
IT CAN ESILY BE PSYCHOTIC,
DELUSIONAL.
HE CAME UP WITH SOMETHING IN HIS
MIND WHERE THESE CHILDREN
REPRESENTED SOMETHING ELSE THAN
WHAT THEY WERE.
THIS SEEMS LIKE A VERY SEVERELY
DISTURBED INDIVIDUAL WHO DID NOT
SNAP IN ONE MINUTE.
>> SOMETHING I WANT TO ASK,
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A BREAK AND
CONTINUE TO TALK ABOUT THIS.
WETHEY WILL DO AN AUTOPSY ON THS
YOUNG MAN AND I'M CURIOUS TO ASK
YOU IF THERE'S ANYTHING IN THE
BRAIN THAT MIGHT EXPLAIN THIS.
WE'LL TAKE A QUICK BREAK.
EXPLAINING A TRAGEDY LIKE THE
ONE IN CONNECTICUT TO CHILDREN
CAN BE HARD.
SCHOOL WEEK IS LOOMING TOMORROW
AND THERE'S A CONVERSATION YOU
MAY WANT TO HAVE.
WHEN WE COME BACK, THE DOCTORS
YOU KNOW AND TRUST EVERY WEEK
ARE GOING TO OFFER YOU TIPS ON
HOW TO BEST DO THAT.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE DESERVES THE GIFT
OF ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF.
THIS SEASON, DISCOVER Aleve.
ALL DAY PAIN RELIEF
WITH JUST TWO PILLS.
>>> ONE OF THE THINGS WE'VE
HEARD THAT'S SO AMAZING FROM THE
FAMILIES AFFECTED BY THIS
TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN IS
FORGIVENESS.
AS MANY OF US GO TO SPIRITUAL
SERVICES TODAY, WE'LL PRAY FOR
THOSE FAMILIES AND TRY TO FIND
IN OUR HEARTS ROOM FOR THE
ASSAILANT, THE ACCUSED.
ONE OF THE THINGS WE WONDER AS
WE MOVE FORWARD IS WE TALK ABOUT
WHAT WE CAN DO IN SCHOOLS TO
MAKE OUR KIDS SAFER AND LEARN
FROM A TRAGEDY LIKE THIS.
WHAT CAN BE LEARNED FROM THIS
SUSPECT?
THIS ASSAILANT.
>> WE CAN ASSUME NOT EVERYBODY
IS THE SAME.
ALL PEOPLE WITH CERTAIN MENTAL
HEALTH CONDITIONS, ASPERGER'S,
AUTISTIC, PERSONALITY DISORDER.
>> MAYBE HE WAS ON DRUGS.
THERE MAY BE SOMETHING THEY'LL
FIND IN THE AUTOPSY ABOUT DRUG
USE.
IT SOUNDS PSYCHOTIC, LIKE HE WAS
THINKING THINGS THAT WEREN'T
RULE.
PLENTY OF PEOPLE HAVE THESE
PROBLEMS THAT DON'T DO SOMETHING
LIKE.
THIS WE DON'T WANT TO BE AFRAID
OF PEOPLE WITH MENTAL HEALTH
CONDITIONS, THIS IS AS NO,
MA'AMICALLY -- ASTRONOMICALLY
SMALL.
THE CHANCES OF A SCHIZOPHRENIC
BECOMING VIOLENT IS VERY SMALL.
THE KIDS THEMSELVES, WE HAVE A
LOT OF PRECEDENT ON THIS.
THERE'S BEEN A NUMBER OF SCHOOL
SHOOTINGS.
THE FIRST THING WE NEED TO TELL
OUR CHILDREN IS, IF THEY ASK,
YOU ANSWER THE QUESTION THAT'S
ASKED.
HOMICIDE, ONLY LESS THAN 1%
OCCUR IN SCHOOLS SO THE CHANCES
OF THIS OCCURRING IN YOUR
CHILD'S SCHOOL IS VERY LOW BUT
OUR CHILDREN NEED TO LEARN
COMPASSION AND EMPATHY FOR THE
VICTIMS.
ALMOST 600 KIDS FILED OUT OF
THAT SCHOOL KNOWING THEY MIGHT
NOT MAKE IT TO CHRISTMAS.
TOLD TO FOLLOW AN ORDER.
WE HAVE A FLIGHT OR FIGHT
RESPONSE WHERE YOU SEE HARM AND
THE FIRST THING YOU DO IS
FREEZE.
ANIMALS DO, WE DO.
THEN WE GET OUTPOURING OF
HORMONES.
>> MY HEATER IS RACE -- HEART IS
RACING JUST AS YOU DESCRIBE THE
FLEE.
THESE ARE LITTLE CHILDREN, HOW
ARE THEY AFFECTED BY A SCENARIO
LIKE THAT?
>> LOOK, WHAT WE'VE -- WE'VE
SAID A LOT OF MAYBES IN THE PAST
AND MARK BRINGS AN IMPORTANT
POINT.
WE DON'T WANT TO JUDGE PEOPLE OR
PROFILE PEOPLE BUT AT SOME POINT
WE NEED TO STOP THIS.
I THINK THE TIME WILL COME THAT
THE MAYBES HAVE TO GO TO THE
SIDE AND WE HAVE TO DEAL WITH
THIS.
SCHOOLS HAVE TO BECOME SAFER.
MONDAY MORNING, THE FIRST
QUESTION WILL BE AM I GOING TO
BE SAFE?
YOU'RE NOT SURE.
NOW, IT IS RARE BUT IT'S ALSO
QUITE OFTEN AND WE'RE SEEING
THEM IN SHOPPING MALLS, IN MOVIE
THEATERS, NOW IN OUR SCHOOL.
THIS HAPPENS ALL THE TIME OF THE
WAY TO DEAL WITH THIS IS STICK
WITH THE KIDS AND WATCH THEM
CAREFULLY.
SIGNS AND SYMPTOMS WILL COME.
EVERYONE DEALS WITH IT IN A
DIFFERENT WAY.
SOME KIDS MAY START TO NOT BE
AFFECTED.
SOME MAY HAVE HEADACHES.
IF THERE'S A CHANGE, A STOMACH
PAIN, IF THEY'RE NOT EATING
WELL.
IT'S OKAY TO BREAK THE RULES AND
LET THEM IN THE BEDROOM AND HUG
THEM AND KEEP THEM WITH YOU.
THEY NEED THE CARE AND LOVE
BECAUSE THEY NEED OUR
PROTECTION.
>> OBVIOUSLY, BESIDES OUR KIDS,
THERE'S NO REPORT YESTERDAY THAT
LANZA RECEIVED PSYCHOLOGICAL
HELP.
WHAT DO YOU DO TO PREVENT THIS
IF YOU SEE SOMETHING LIKE THIS?
>> FIRST YOU HAVE TO HOPEFULLY
HAVE MORE OF A REACHOUT PROGRAM
FOR PEOPLE WITH MENTAL ILLNESS
AND GET THEM IN TREATMENT.
WE'VE SEEN TOO MANY SHOOTINGS,
THE ONE IN COLORADO, WHERE THERE
WERE WARNING SIGNS THAT
PSYCHIATRIC PERSONNEL
OVERLOOKED.
IN TERMS OF THE KIDS, FOR THE
KIDS THAT ARE SURVIVORS, PTSD IN
ADULTS USUALLY SEE FLASHBACKS,
FOR KIDS, THEY MAY WORK IT OUT
IN PLAY.
THEY MAY GET ANGRY, SAD, DIS
ASSOCIATED AND FEEL ALONE.
THESE ARE THE SURVIVORS.
STUDIES SHOW PEOPLE IN THE
COMMUNITY HAVE THIS PROBLEM AND
THERE'S SOMETHING CALLED
VICARIOUS DISTRESS.
WE NEED TO LOOK OUT FOR THE
SURVIVORS, AND PEOPLE IN THE
UNITED STATES.
>> WE'LL HAVE MORE ON WHAT YOU
CAN TELL YOUR CHILDREN AND HOW
YOU CAN DEAL WITH THAT AND
PREVENT THESE HORRIBLE TRAGEDIES
FROM OCCURRING IN THE FUTURE.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
>>> BACK NOW WITH "SUNDAY HOUSE
CALL."
ADAM LANZA'S BROTHER SAID'D
PERSONALITY DISORDER.
WE TALKED ABOUT THE STRESSES IN
HIS LIFE.
HOW DO YOU RECOGNIZE DEEP
PROBLEMS IN SOMEONE YOU LOVE?
WHERE DO YOU GET HELP AND CAN
YOU FORCE SOMEONE TO GET HELP?
WHAT HAPPENS IF SOMEONE'S
TROUBLED AND IN YOUR HOUSEHOLD?
WHAT CAN PEOPLE DO?
>> WE NEED TO SUPPORT THEM.
WE NEED TO CARE FOR THEM.
NOT LEAVE THEM ALONE.
I THINK THE PROBLEM HAPPENS --
WE'RE GOING TO LEARN MORE AS THE
STORY PANS OUT BUT THERE WAS A
DIVORCE IN 2009.
SO THE LEADING FIGURE IN THE
FAMILY IS GONE.
THE FATHER IS NOT IN THE
PICTURE.
THE BROTHER HASN'T TALKED TO HIM
FOR ABOUT TWO YEARS.
THAT'S A HUGE IMPACT.
MOM IS WORKING, TRYING TO RUN
THE FAMILY.
YOU HAVE A LOANER, SHY -- LONER,
SHY KID WITH A PSYCHOLOGICAL
BACKGROUND EXPOSED TO RIFLES.
THE DEBATE ON WHETHER YOU SHOULD
HAVE GUNS IS NOT FOR TODAY.
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLES, THEY'RE
NOT SAFE TO HAVE IN THE HANDS OF
SOMEONE WHO IS NOT COMPLETELY
INTACT MENTALLY.
PLUS THE FACT THERE'S A HUGE
PRESSURE IN SOCIETY ON THIS KID.
PERHAPS THERE'S BULLYING WE
DON'T KNOW ABOUT.
WHEN HE WALKED IN THE HALLWAY,
HE WOULD GO TO THE CORNER AND
HIDE.
IF YOU DIAGNOSE IT, YOU GET
HELP, WE CAN PREVENT IT.
>> APPARENTLY HE WAS TAKEN OUT
OF SCHOOL AND HOMESCHOOLED AT
SOME POINT.
SHOULD THE SCHOOL SYSTEM HAVE
CAUGHT IT AND ADDRESSED IT?
THEY MAY HAVE.
>> YOU LOOK FOR CHANGES IN
BEHAVIOR.
IS SOMEONE THAT WAS SLEEPING AT
NIGHT NOT SLEEPING.
ARE THEY GETTING OUT OF BED?
ARE THEY DEPRESSED?
THERE WAS A REPORT HE CARRIED A
BRIEFCASE WHERE BEFORE HE
CARRIED SOMETHING ELSE.
HE WAS REMOVED FROM PEOPLE.
ARE PEOPLE'S SOCIAL PATTERNS
CHANGING.
>> THE PARENTS ARE TRYING TO
PROTECT THEIR KIDS.
MOM AND DAD ARE TRYING TO
THEY'RE NOT GOING TO REPORT THEM
TO THE PRINCIPALS, SO THE
QUESTION IS HOW DO YOU REPORT
THEM.
HOW DO YOU SAY WE HAVE A
PROBLEM?
>> YOUR POINT ABOUT GUNS IS
EXCELLENT.
THE IDEA THIS MOTHER HAS
OUTRAGEOUS ASSAULT WEAPONS IN A
HOUSE WITH A SON WITH MENTAL
HEALTH PROBLEMS.
>> SHE'S A VICTIM HERSELF.
>> LET'S GO TO ONE MORE TOPIC IF
WE CAN ON THIS.
WHEN WE COME BACK, MANY PARENTS
ARE GRAPPLING ON HOW TO TALK TO
THEIR KIDS AND THE DOCTORS HAVE
FIGURED OUT HOW TO DO IT WITH
THEIRS ABOUT A SHOOTING THAT
HAPPENED AS A PLACE THAT'S
SUPPOSED TO BE SAFE.
VALUABLE TIPS ON HOW TO START
THAT CONVERSATION.
THE DOCTORS WANT TO WEIGH IN ON
THE HEROES, THE TEACHERS THAT
SPRUNG INTO ACTION.
[ sniffs ] I HAVE A COLD.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
>> JAMIE: TALKING TO YOUR KIDS
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED AS YOU
PREPARE THEM TO GO BACK TO
SCHOOL ON MONDAY.
DOCTOR, YOU TOLD US HOW MUCH OR
HOW LITTLE YOU COLD YOUR KIDS.
WHAT ADVICE DO YOU HAVE?
>> FOR KID, DON'T BE AFRAID TO
TELL YOUR PARENTS.
ANYTHING IS NORMAL.
ANYTHING THAT'S BOTHERING YOU,
SHARE WITH YOUR PARENTS.
AND THEY MAY NEED TO GET YOU
SUPPORT.
AT THE SCENE, WE ARE SEEING YALE
UNIVERSITY BRINGING IN A CRISIS
CENTER, WHICH IS TERRIFIC,
HELPING A LOT IN THE LONG TERM.
BUT I WANT TO POINT OUT ABOUT
THE COURAGE OF THE TEACHERS AT
THE SCHOOL.
I WANT MY KIDS AND EVERY KID TO
FOCUS ON THE COURAGE OF THE
TEACHERS WHO BROUGHT THE KIDS TO
SAFETY.
THE SAME PART OF THE BRAIN THAT
FEAR IS IN.
>> JAMIE: ADRENALIN, PRACTICE
DRILLS AND CONCERN FOR THE
CHILDREN LED THEM TO PAY THE
ULTIMATE SACRIFICE.
>> WE NEED TO LIMIT THE