>> MY DAUGHTER EMILY.
SHE IS STAND GIVING LOVE AND
STIPULATE TO ALL OF THOSE
VICTIMS BECAUSE THAT IS I
TYPE OF PERSON SHE S. NOT
BECAUSE OF PARENTING MY WIFE
AND I COULD HAVE DONE, BUT
BECAUSE THOSE WERE GIFTS GIVEN
TO HER BY HER HEAVENLY FATHER.
>> A VERY POWERFUL EXPRESSION
FROM ROBBY PARKER.
HE'S THE FATHER OF SIX YEAR
OLD EMLY PARKER, ONE OF THE
VICTIMS IN THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
FEW TOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> HELLO, I AM MIKE HUCKABEE.
I AM COMING TO YOU LIVE IN NEW
YORK CITY .
OUR NATION IS IN SHOCK OVER
THE SENSELESS AND UNSPEAKABLE
TRAGEDY THAT TOOK PLACE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THE SHOOTER KILLED HIS MOTHER
IN HER HOME AND THEN TO A
ELEMENTARY COOL WHERE HE GUND
DOWN 20 OPPORTUNITIS AND TEACH
ARES BEFORE HE TOOK HIS OWN
LIFE .
MOLLY?
NTHE COMMUNITY HAS BEEN
PULLING TOGETHER SINCE THIS
HORRIFIC MASSACRE.
THERE ARE NUMEROUS VIGILS AND
WE ARE GETTING WORD THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS IT JOINING
THE COMMUNITY AND AN
INTERFAITH VIGIL.
THER JOINING TOGETHER AND
HEALING THE COMMUNITY.
IT IS IT A DIFFICULT AND LONG
ROAD AHEAD WHEN YOU THINK
ABOUT THE VICTIMS IN THIS
CASE.
AND SO MANY LIVES LOST AND 12
LITTLE GIRLS AND EIGHT LITTLE
BOYS AND SIX WOMEN.
TWO OF THE WOMEN KILLED WERE
SO YOUNG.
BEGINNING THEIR CAREERS IN
EDUCATION .
IN THEIR TWENS AND ONE JUST 30
YEARS OLD AND ALL OF THESE
WOMEN TRYING TO PROTECT THE
CHILDREN.
THE YOUNGEST VICTIM NAMED
NOAH.
YOU LOOK AT THE LIST OF THE
CHILDREN'S NAMES AND THE NAMES
YOU HEAR IN CLASSROOMS ALL
OVER AMERICA.
CHARLOTTE, AND ANNA, AND
DANIEL.
TINY LITTLE PEOPLE CUT DOWN
BEFORE THEY SO MUCH MUCH LIFE.
THAT'S WHAT PRESIDENT OBAMA
TALK BODY THE LIVES THAT WERE
CUT SHORT.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER TALKING
ABOUT THE TRAGEDY AND GIVING A
PICTURE OF WHAT HAPPENED IN
THE SCHOOL.
NOT UNEXPECTED DETAILS.
WE KNEW THEY WERE GOING TO BE
HORRIBLE BUT THE EXTENT OF THE
DETAIL WAS CLINICAL.
NEARLY ALL OF THE VICTIMS HAD
MULTIPLE GUN HOT.
THREE-LEN GUN SHOT WOUNDS AND
THOSE ARE THE FOLKS HE HAD A
CHANCE TO EXAMINE HIMSELF.
HE PARTICIPATED IN 7 OF THE
EXAMS PERSONALLY.
THE PAPERWORK IS COMPLETED AND
NOW, IT IS TIME FOR THE
FAMILIES TO HAVE A CHANCE TO
SEE THEIR LOVED ONES AND
EXPERIENCE THE GREAT LOSS AND
IN THE COMING DAYS, FUNERALS
AND MEMORIAL SERVICES AND A
VERY LONG ROAD TO RECOVERY FOR
THE COMMUNITY.
GOVERNOR.
>> MOLLY, THANK YOU FOR YOUR
REPORT THERE IN NEWTOWN.
>> MAYBE IT IS SIMPLEP THE
ATTEMPT TO EXPRESS OUR
COLLECTIVE SHOCK WHEN WE SAY
WE ARE TRYING TO MAKE SENSE OF
THE HORRIFIC SHOOTING IN THE
SANDY HOOKS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
IT IS IT NOT SENSE TO A
RATIONAL HUMAN BEING.
THE GOVERNOR MALLOY GOT IT
RIGHT WHEN HE SAID ERIL
VISITED THE COMMUNITY.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SPOKE MORE AS
A PARENT THAN A POLITICIAN AND
QUOTED THE BIBLE TO BRING
COMFORT TO THE NATION.
CHURCHES WERE FILLED IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT LAST
NIGHT AS CANDLELIGHT VIGILS
WERE HELD TO GRIEVE FOR THE 27
INNOCENT PEOPLE KILLED AND
THOSE SHATTERED BY THE CRAZED
CARNAGE.
ON FRIDAY, NEAL CAVUTED ME,
WHERE WAS GOD IN WE HAVE
SYSTEMATICALLY REMOVED GOD
FROM OUR SCHOOLS AND PUBLIC
ACCOUNT ACTIVITIES AND AT THE
MOMENT OF THE CALAMITY WE
WONDER WHERE IT WAS.
THE LIBERAL WAVE HAD A VIOLENT
AND JUMPED TO THE CONCLUSION
THAT IF I SAID PRAYER WAS IN
SCHOOL THE SHOOTING WOULD NOT
HAVE HAPPEN.
I SAID NOTHING OF THE SORT.
IT IS FAR MORE THAN PRAYER AND
BIBLE READING.
IT IS IT THE FACT THAT PEOPLE
SUE A CITY SO WE HAVE NO MAJOR
16 OR CHRISTMAS CAROL CHURCHES
AND CHRISTIAN OWNED BUSINESSES
ARE TOLD TO SURRENDER THE
VALUES UNDER THE EDICT OF THE
GOVERNMENT ORDERS TO PROVIDE
TAX-FUNDED ABORTION PILLS .
WE SAY THINGS ARE SINFUL AND
SAY THEY ARE DISORDERS AND
SOMETIMES WE SAY THEY ARE
NORMAL AND HAVE TO ABANDON BED
ROCK MEMIORAL TRUTHS, WE WERE,
WHERE WAS GOD?
WHY ESCORTED HIM OUT OF OUR
CULTURE AND MARCHED HIM OUT OF
THE PUBLIC SQUARE AND THEN
SURPRISED THAT A CULTURE
REFLECTS WHAT IT IS IT BECOME.
AS SOON AS THE TRAGEDY
UNFOLDED HE SHOWED UP.
IN THE LIVES OF TEACHERS WHO
PUT THEIR LIVES BETWEEN THE
GUNMEN AND THE STUDENTS AND IN
POLICEMEN WHO RUSH SCHOOL NOT
KNOWING IF THEY WOULD BE MET
WITH A BARAGE OF STUDENTS.
AND HUGS AND TIERCE OF PARENTS
AND TEACHERS THAT LIVED
THROUGH THE SLAUGHTER AND
OVERFLOWED CHURCH SERVICES
WHERE PEOPLE LIT CANDLES AND
PRAYED HE SHOWED UP IN THE
WHITE HOUSE WHERE THE
PRESIDENT ENVOKED HIS NAME AND
QUOTED FROM HIS BOOK THEN IN A
FEW DAYS, WE'LL GOD TO EXCUSE
HIMSELF.
AND ANNOUNCE IN OUR ARROGANT
PRIDE THAT WE HAVE EVOLVED
BEYOND NEEDING HIM AND SOMEONE
WILL SUGGEST WE HAVE A LAW TO
STOP THIS.
WE DON'T HAVE TO PASS A NEW
ONE.
THERE IS ONE THAT WORKS IF WE
TEACH AND OBSERVE IT.
SHAW SHALT NOT KILL.
THERE ARE NINE OTHERS.
BUT TO TELL THEM ABOUT THAT
WOULD REQUIRE BRINGING GOD
BACK AND WE KNOW HOW
UNACCEPTABLE THAT MIGHT BE.
GERALDO RIVARY IS STANDING BY
IN NEWTOWN, BUT MORE
IMPORTANTLY GERALDO, I CAN'T
THINK OF ANY MAJOR AMERICAN
TRANNEL DEE THAT YOU HAVE NOT
SEEN UP CLOSE AND PERSONAL IN
THE LAST 40 YEARS.
HOW DOES THIS ONE COMPARE TO
THE TRAGIC EVENTS THAT YOU
COVER AS A REPORTER IN THE
PAST FOUR DECADES.
>> GOVERNOR, LET ME IF I MAY,
START BY YOU KNOW, GIVING YOU
A ELECTRONICALLY A BIG EMBRACE
AND AGREEING WITH YOU.
THIS CRIME, THIS CRIME, THIS
ATROCITY WAS A GODLESS ACT AND
THAT THIS PERPETRATOR WAS IN
EVERY WAY THE DEVIL INCARNATE
HERE ON EARTH.
HE WAS THE AGENT OF THE
APOCALYPSE.
IP AM NOT A PREACHER, I HAVE
AN UNUSUAL AS YOU KNOW
THELOGICAL BACKGROUND, MY
JEWISH MOTHER AND CATHOLIC
FATHER.
BUT IT IS IMPOSSIBLE FOR ME TO
MISS THE POINT THAT WERE THIS
A FAITH-BASED YOUNG MAN, HE
COULD NOT POSSIBLY HAVE
PERPETRATED THE EVIL.
THIS WAS NOT JUST CRIME.
THIS WAS EVIL.
THIS WAS DEBASE.
THIS WAS SOMETHING THAT SO
UTTERLY BEYOND THE REALM OF
APPROPRIATE CIVILIZED CONDUCT.
THIS WAS SOMEONE WHO WANTED TO
INFLICT PAIN AND IN INFLICTING
PAIN, HE CHOSE THE MOST
VULNERABLE VICTIMS, SIX YEARS
OLD AND 7 YEARS OLD IN FIRST
GRADE AND TOOK THAT BIG GUN
AND POSING AS IF HE WAS A
NINJA CAR WAR GARBED IN BLACK
AND STUCK IT TO THE TERRIFIED
CHILDREN AND ENDED THEIR LIVES
AND SHOT THEM AGAIN AND AGAIN
AND AGAIN.
THIS IS IT, GOVERNOR, THAT NO
CORRESPONDANT HAS SEEN THIS
KIND OF CARNAGE HERE IN NEW
ENGLAND, IN A BEAUTIFUL 300
YEAR OLD COMMUNITY TO WHICH
PEOPLE FLOCK WOULD FOR ITS
SAFETY AND ITS SECURITY AND
TRADITIONS AND CHURCHES, AND
ITS SURRENITY.
HE PERPETRATED AN OBSCENITY.
IF THIS IS NOT THE DEVIL AT
WORK, I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT IS,
GOCH GOCH.
>> I CAN'T IMAGINE THE GRIEF
AND PAIN THAT YOU HAVE SEEN
THERE.
AS YOU HAVE BEEN THERE, PEOPLE
APPRECIATE THE MEDIA BRINGING
ATTENTION TO THE PLIGHT AND
THEN THERE COMES A TIME WHEN
THEY WANT PEOPLE TO LEAVE AND
THEY NEED PEACE.
ARE THEY THEY AT THAT POINT OR
DO THEY APPRECIATE THE
ATTENTION THAT IS IT FOC OUSED
ON NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> I HAVE TO WORRY THAT THIS
WAY.
I GOT HERE LATE INTENTIONALLY
I HAVE BEEN AN OBSERVER MUCH
MORE AN OBSERVER THAN A
REPORTER.
I FELT AN ABSOLUTE QUEASINESS
ABOUT GOING UP TO PEOPLE
ANDING THEM.
WE USED INTERMEDIARIES TO SEE
IF THEY SHARED THE STORE
STORSES.
CRIG MY BROTHER WAS HERE ALL
DAY YESTERDAY AND SOME
RESPONDED WITH BITTERNESS AT
THE INTRUSION.
AND OTHERS ARE THANKFUL FOR
THE COMPASSION AND THE
SUPPORT.
I AM SURE THAT THE HEALER IN
CHIEF, AND THE PRESIDENT GETS
HERE TOMORROW NIGHT, HE WILL
BE ABLE TO LET EVERYONE IN THE
COUNT, WHO SAID THEY DON'T
KNOW AND MOST OF THEM DO, THAT
THE WORLD ASK NATION IS UNITE
THAT WE ARE ALL PARENTS OF
THESE CHILDREN AND TONIGHT, AS
PEOPLE WATCH, AND HUG THEIR
CHILDREN, THAT'S THE BEST WAY
WE CAN FIGHT BACK AGAINST THIS
OBSCENE DEAL AND MINI
HOLOCAUST.
I NEVER USE THE EXPRESSION
HOLOCAUST IT CONNOTES THE MOST
DREADFUL THING THAT HAPPENS IN
THE HUMAN SUSPICIOUS.
THAT WAS FOR THE 20 CHILDREN
THE HOLOCAUST AND THAT EVIL
THAT THIS MAN PERPETRATED
AGAINST THEM WAS AS MUCH LIKE
THE EVIL THE NAZIES
PERPETRATED AS KIDNAPPING I
CAN THINK MUCH.
>> GERALDO, THANK YOU FOR
JOINING US IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
YOU WILL HAVE A LIVE SHOW
LATER THIS EVENING FROM
NEWTOWN.
AND WE KNOW FOLKS WILL WANT TO
WATCH THAT AT 10 O'CLOCK
EASTERN TIME.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
WILEHEAR FROM A MOTHER WHOSE
SON WAS AT SANDY HOOK AND HE
WAS IN THE SCHOOL DURING THE
SHOOTING YESTERDAY.
THAT'S NEXT
>> AS PARENTS OF THE STUNES IN
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
GOT THE WORD OF THE SHOOTING,
THEY RUSHED TO THE SCHOOL AND
NEARBY FIRE HOUSE AND FEARING
THE WORST AND HOPING AND
PRAYING FOR THE BEST.
THAT'S WHERE CHRIS TEEN
WILFRED FOUND HER SENYEAR OLD
SON SAFE AND SOUND AND SHE
JOINS US ON THE PHONE, CHRIS
TEEN, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
IT IS IT A DIFFICULT TIME FOR
YOU AND I APPRECIATE YOU BEING
WILLING TO VISIT WITH US ABOUT
IT >> WHEN YOU FIRST HEARD
SOMETHING HAPPENED IN THE
SCHOOL, WHERE WERE YOU AND
WHAT DID YOU HEAR AND WHAT DID
YOU DO?
>> I WAS AT HOME SITTING AT MY
KITCHEN TABLE WITH MY HUSBAND.
HE DECIDE TOD WORK FROM HOME
YESTERDAY.
A NEIGHBOR HAD COME OVER TO
PICK UP A CHRISTMAS PRESENT I
HAD AT MY HOUSE FOR HER SON.
AND WE RECEIVED AN AUTOMATED
PHONE CALL THAT THE SCHOOLS
WERE IN LOCK DOWN DUE TO A
REPORTED SHOOTING.
SHE GOT ON THE PHONE TO HER
HUSBAND AND HE SAID HE THOUGHT
IT WAS SANDY HOOK WE PULLED UP
ON THE COMPUTER THAT IT WAS
SANDY HOOK.
AND SHE LEFT TO GO TO HER
HUSBAND, AND WE LOADED OUR TWO
YEAR OLD IN THE CAR AND HEADED
TO SCHOOL .
>> YOU HAD NO IDEA ON YOUR WAY
TO SANDY HOOK WHERE YOUR SON
WAS OKAY OR NOT, DO YOU?
>> NO, NO.
WE HAD NO IDEA.
ALL WE COULD DO IS HOPE AND
PRAY.
THAT HE WAS OKAY.
HOW DUFIRST FIND OUT THAT YOUR
SON WAS OKAY?
>> WE PUMED UP ALONG WITH
MANY, MANY OTHER PARENTS ALL
ARRIVING AND CONVERGING ON THE
MAIN ROAD AND START TOTTED RUN
DOWN THE DIRT ROD THAT WE
FOUND TO THE SCHOOL, THE
LITTLE SIDE ROAD.
AND WE WERE IMMEDIATELY
DIRECTED BY THE POLICE THAT
OH, CHILDREN WERE EVACUATED TO
THE FIRE HOUSE.
AND JUST RAN IN THERE AND
STARTED TO FRANTICALLY LOOK AS
EVERYBODY WAS PACKED IN THERE.
YOU KNOW, SPOTTED HIS TEACH
ARE FIRST.
HE'S OKAY HE'S RIGHT HERE AND
GOT HIM OFF OF THE GROUND AND
GAY HIM TO ME.
>> OH, I CAN'T IMAGINE CHRIS
TEEN AS A PARENT.
IP JUST CAN'T GET MY ARMS
AROUND THE EMOTION THAT YOU
MUST HAVE HAD WHEN YOU SAW
YOUR SON WAS OKAY.
I AM ASSUMING YOU GRABBED HIM
AND HUGGED HIM ALMOST TO THE
POINT OF SQUEEZING THE AIR OUT
OF HIM.
HE IS LIKE I AM OKAY.
I DONE CRY.
I WAS BRAVE.
AND YOU KNOW, I AM OKAY.
AND I SAID OKAY.
AND PASSED HIM TO MY HUSBAND
SO HE COULD HUG HIM AND THEN
MY THOUGHTS WENT TO ONE OF MY
BEST FRIEND'S DAUGHTERS WHO I
KNEW WAS AT WORK AND I
IMMEDIATELY STARTED TO LOOK
FOR HER AND FOUND HER AND TOOK
HER.
AND TOLD HER MANAGER ON THE
PHONE WITH HER MOTHER.
NTHAT MUST HAVE BEEN ONE HAPPY
CONVERSATION.
HAD THAT MOTHER KNOWN ABOUT
THE PHONE CALL.
YES, HAD KNOWN.
SHE HAD KNOWN.
SHE HAD CALL WOULD WHILE WE
WERE ON THE WAY TO THE SCHOOL.
HOW DO YOU IXPLAIN TO YOUR SON
WHAT HAPPENED.
THAT IS A HORRIBLE THING TO
EXPLAIN SOMETHING SO HEINOUS
AND EVIL TO A CHILD IN A WAY
THAT MAYBE HE COULD UNDERSTAND
IT.
>> WE JUST TOLD HIM THAT, THAT
VERY BAD MAN CAME IN THE
SCHOOL AND HURT A LOT OF
PEOPLE.
AND YOU KNOW, HE WAS EXPLAINED
AND WE FOUND OUT NAMES OF
PEOPLE THAT HE WAS FRIENDS
WITH AND KNEW, WE LET HIM
KNOW.
AND YOU KNOW.
KEEP CHECKING IN WITH HIM.
I HIM ONCE AN HOUR HOW HE IS
DOING AND IF HES OKAY.
AND JUST TELL HIM IF HEMENT TO
TALK WE ARE HERE.
>> CHRIS TEEN, THERE IS NOT A
PARENT IN AMERICA THAT IS NOT
AM SOY GLAD YOU AND YOUR SON
ARE OKAY AND ALL OF YOUR
FAMILY.
I KNOW IT IS A HARD TIME AND
YOU HAVE KNOWN TEACHERS AND
OTHER KIDS WHO ARE NOT OKAY.
I APPRECIATE YOU LETTING US
INVADE YOUR PRIVACY AND
THARCHING YOU FOR LETTING US
UNDERSTAND WHAT YOU WENT
THROUGH.
NTHANK YOU.
>> THAT WAS CHRIS TEEN
WILFORD.
HER SON 7 YEAR OLD WAS SAFE.
WHAT A HORRIBLE EXPERIENCE.
AND WHAT ARE DETECTIVES DOING
NOW TO PIECE TOGETHER WHY THE
SHOOTING HAPPENED?
WEELERWILL HELP ANSWER THAT.
>> IT WAS UNREAL AND I CAN'T
BELIEVE IT THAT IT IS IT TRUE.
I CAN'T FATHOM THIS.
NOTHING MAKES SENSE LIKE THIS.
THIS IS IT SENSELESS.
>> STILL NO MOTIVE KNOWN AS TO
WHY THE SHOOTER DID WHAT HE
DID BEFORE TAKING HIS OWN
LIFE.
WHAT CLUES ARE PEOPLE LOOKING
FOR.
JOHN IS A POLICE DETECTIVE.
JOHN, BEFORE I GET IN THE
EVIDENCE GATHERING WHICH I
KNOW THE POLICE ARE THROUGH
NOW.
I DON'T THINK MOST PEOPLE
UNDERSTAND.
WHEN THE POLICE OFFICERS FIRST
AROUND ON THE SCREEN LIKE THEY
DID IN SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
THEY HAD NO IDEA WHAT THEY MAY
FACE.
THEY MAY FACE ONE GUN OR FIVE
GUNS OR EXPLOSIVES.
THEY RUN IN UATION WHERE THEY
MAY HAVE TO MAKE A SPLIT
SECOND DECISION WHERE THEY MAY
ACT THE LIVES OF KIDS.
>> IT IS TRUE.
YOU NIVER CAN FULLY PREPARE
BECAUSE YOU NEVER KNOW WHAT
THE SCENARIO IS.
WE HAVE EMERGENCY ACTION PLANS
FOR THESE SHOOTERS.
AND THIS IS WHAT THE SITUATION
WAS.
AND WE HAVE POLICE OFFICERS
AND DETECTIVES AND UNITS THAT
TRAIN FOR THIS ALL OF THE TIME
FOR THIS TYPE OF SCENARIO.
AND SO WHEN THEY TURN OUT.
THEY ESTABLISH A PERIMETER AND
SET UP A MOBILE COMMAND BASE
AND PLOY THE TROOPS AND VET
INFORMATION AS IT COMES IN.
AND THEY WILL USUALLY WORK IN
A MINIMUM OF FOUR TEEMS THAT
GO THROUGH THE DOOR AND DO A
GRID SEARCH.
AND MAYBE THEY WILL ACCESS TO
POIGNS OF THE BUILDING AND
BEING AWARE OF THE CROSS FIRE
SCENARIO TO STAY AWAY FROM
THAT.
THEY GO IN AND THEY DON'T KNOW
IF THE DOORS ARE BOOBY TRAPPED
OR IF THERE IS MORE THAN ONE
SHOOTER.
AND THOSE PEOPLE MAY NOT HAVE
ALL OF THE INFORMATION.
AFTER COLUMBINE.
ONE OF THE CHANGES IN DEALING
WITH LAW ENFORCEMENTS, AS IN
COLUMBINE THEY WAITED A MINUTE
TO ASSESS WHAT WAS GOING O.
AND THE PROTOCALL IS YOU GO IN
AND TRY TO GET TO THE SHOOTER
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
AND THAT MEEPS THE FIRST GUYS
IN THERE ARE PUTTING THEIR IN
HARM'S WAYS.
A CRIME LIKE THIS IS USUAL LIE
DONE WITHIN FIVE MINUTES.
YOU DON'T HAVE TIME TO ASSESS.
YOU ASSESS ON THE RUN SO YEAH,
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT IS ON THE
OTHER SIDE.
YOU WORK OUT A PLAN BEFORE
HAND AND YOU ARE ANALYZING
YOUR STRAT STRAT ON --
STRATEGY ON THE RUN.
24 HOURS PASSED BEFORE THE
BODIES WERE REMOVED AND A LOT
OF INTENSE FORENSIC WORK WAS
GOING ON.
HELP US TO UNDERSTAND, WHAT IS
IT THAT THE POLICE ARE DOING
BEHIND THE CLOSED DOORS,
OBVIOUSLY NO CAMERAS ARE GOING
IN THERE AND NO ONE WILL GET
IN THERE IS IT EVAPORATE THAT
YOU TABE YOUR CRIME SCENE.
IT WAS A CONTAINED CRIME 69
AND BEHIND THE SCENES, THEY
ARE LOOKING AT THE PROCESS IN
THE CRIME SCENE AND FOREPSICS
THAT THEY ARE RECOVERING.
MATCHING THOSE ROUNDS TO THE
GUN.
THE MOST IMPORTANT THING IF
YOU ARE FINDING A ROUND.
AND NO GUN.
IS THERE A SECOND SHOOTER IN
THE BUILDING OR MAYBE -- OUT
IN THE WORLD.
THAT YOU KNOW, NOW IS STILL A
THREAT TO OTHERS.
YOU WANT TO MACH SURE THERE IS
ONE SHOOTER AND YOU HAVELET
EVIDENCE. AND MAKE SURE YOU
ESTABLISH A TIME LINE TO THAT.
OF COURSE, ONCE THE SHOOTER
KILL SAYS HIMSELF .
ALL OF THAT IS SECOND HARE TO
TABING ONE OR TWO SHOOTERSMENT
ONE FINAL QUESTION.
EALLY YOU HAVE BEEN A POLICE
OFFICER FOR A LONG TIME.
CAN EVER BE PREPARED TO SIGH
THE DEATH OF SO MANY CHILDREN?
>> I CAN'T FATHOM IT.
RIGHT NOW THEY HAVE
BEREAVEMENT CONTRACTORS AND
THAT IS IT NOT ONLY FOR THE
FAMILIES AND VICTIM A CHILDREN
BUT THE PARENTS AND SURVIVING
CHILDREN AND SCHOOL OFFICIALS
AND PLICE OFFICERS.
THEY ARE TRAUMATIZED.
THEY HAVE CHILDREN AT HOME.
AND SCHOOL OFFICIALS HAVE
CHILDREN AT HOME.
SURVIVOR'S GUILT.
YOU DIDN'T WANT THEM TO SEE
THEZ THIPPINGS.
NI HAVE TO SAY IT IS DIFFERENT
WITH TEEN IT IS OR ADULTINGS.
BUT IT LATELY IS.
NIT IS.
>> Y JUNE, MY HEART GOES OUT
TO ALL OF THE COPS.
THEY ARE HUMACHINE, TOO.
NWE PRAY THAT GOD GIVES THEM
TRENTH TO COPE WITH THE LOSS.
ING UP A FATHER WHOSE WAS
KILLED IN THE COLUMBINE
TRAGEDY.
WE'LL EXPLAIN.
WITH THE
LATEST ON THE SCHOOL SHOOTINGS
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> WE ARE BACK WITH A SPECIAL
LIVE EDITION OF HUCKABEE.
WE'LL SHOW YOU GRACE MCDONALD.
GRACEY'S FAMILY ISSUED A
STATEMENT.
WE ARE OVERWHELMED WITH THE
OUTLETPOWERING AND LOVE AND
SUPPORT FOR SO MANY PEOPLE.
OUR GRACE WAS THE LOVE AND
LIGHT OF OUR FAMILY.
WORDS CANNOT ADEQUATELY
EXPRESS OUR SENSE OF LOSS.
DARRYL SCOTT'S DAUGHTER RACHEL
WAS ONE OF THE 13 VICTIMS OF
THE BINE BOIN VICTIMS IN APRIL
20TH, 1999.
>> DARRYL, I APPRECIATE YOU
BEING HERE.
IT CAUSES YOU TO RELIVE
PAINFUL MOMENTS 13 YEARS AGO.
I WANT TO BEGIN BYING WHAT
THAT MOMENT WAS LIKE WHEN YOU
REALIZED THAT RACHEL, YOUR
DAUGHTER WAS ONE OF THE
VICTIMS IN THE COLUMBINE
SHOOTING?
I THINK THE FIRST THING THAT
HAPPENS, YOU EXPERIENCE SUCH A
SHOCK AND THERE IS IT A
CERTAIN AMOUNT OF DISBELIEF.
I KEPT EXPECTING HER TO WALK
THROUGH THE DOOR AND EXPECTING
TO SEE HER AND IT TOOK A WHILE
FOR IT TO HIT DEAD CENTER THAT
SHE WAS GONE.
THAT HAPPENS A LOT WITH
PARENTS WHO DON'T EXPECT TO
LOSE YOUR CHILD.
YOU NEVER EXPECT IT TO HAPPEN.
IT WAS A NIGHTMARE.
NYOU KNOW, THE TOUGHEST THING
TO WHAT TO SAY TO THE PARENTS.
IF YOU BE IN THEIR HOMES
TONIGHT AND SIT ACROSS FROM
THEM AND WHAT WOULD YOU SAY
THAT COMES FROM THE RARE
PEOPLE IN THE COUNTRY WHO CAN
SAY I DO KNOW HOW YOU FEEL IN
>> THEY DON'T NEED ME.
THEY NEED THEIR FRIEND FAMILY.
BUT IF I WAS IN THE SWADINGS,
I WOULD PUT MY ARM ATHEM AND
CRY WITH THEM.
THERE IS IT NOTHING YOU CAN
SAY IN THAT MOMENT.
I WOULD NOT HAVE WANTED A
STRANGER TRYING TO TELL ME
SOMETHING OR GIVE ME INPUT.
YOU JUST HAVE TO GRIEVE.
BEST TING TO DO IS GRIEVE WITH
THEM ASK LOVE THEM.
IT IS SIMPLE ADVICE BUT THE
BEST.
NRACHEL WASED DO YOU BELIEVE
IN GOD.
SHE SAID YES.
SHE COULD HAVE SAID NO .
AND THEN SHE WAS KILLED.
HAVE THERE BEEN TIMES WHEN YOU
HAVE BEEN MAD AT GOL AND BLAME
HIM?
>> NO, ACTUALLY .
YOU DONE GET PREPARED IN A
CRISIS.
THE PREP ADINGS HAS TO BE
THERE BEFORE YOU GO IN A
CRISIS AND OUR FAMILY IS IT A
FAMILY OF FAITH.
AND I FELT EVEN BEFORE RACHEL
DIED, I FELT SOMETHING TO
HAPPEN.
I FOAL LIKE THERE IS SOMETHING
STIRRING IN ME AND WE ARE
BEING PREPARED FOR.
AND WHEN THE TRAMMING TRAG
HAPPENED.
RAY METROPOLITANOR IN PLILIFE
HAD TOLD ME MANY, MANY YIRES
AGO.
IF YOU CAN BE A SEE THROUGHER.
AND NOT A LOOK ATER HAD YOU
WILL HAVE PURPOSE MEETING.
NYOU WILLEE THE HAND MUCH
GOOD.
>> YOU HAVE DONE THAT.
YOU TARTED A INSURANCE TO TRY
TO REACH KIDS IN TALK TO THIM.
YOU TALK TO 18 STUDENTS IN
AMERICA.
THAT YOU HAVOIN AGAIN BECAUSE.
GRIEVE YOU EXPERIENCED.
NIT IS MISUNDERSTANDING AND
THE BILL OF RIGHTS BY A LOT OF
PEOPLE IN OUR NATION .
WE A RELIGIOUS.
WE ARE A NONPROFIT RELIGIOUS
ORGANIZATION.
WE HAVE PRESENTERS AND EACH
YEAR WE REACH THREE MILLION.
AND WE DID ASEMBEE TRAPING.
THE AND WHY TALK ABOUT MATTER.
IN LOIT AND WE TALK ABOUT BE A
SEE THROUGHERS AND LOOLLY.
ERB IS MORE IMPORTANT THRAN
THE WE TALK ABOUT THE
PRINCIPLES.
BUT RACHEL 'STORY CHANGES
THEIRS.
WE HAVE HAD 500 RIRENED IN THE
YEARS.
AND THEY ARE TELLS US IF IT
CHOSEN WILBURN WILBERKS ER.
>> HE FELT LIKE HE WAS LED TO
RHETOR MANNERS ENGLAPPED AND
HE MUCHED TO -- HE RESTORED
MANORS TO CHILDREN.
AND SLAVERY WASAL POLISH .
AND THAT SAME AFTER HIS DEATH.
WONDERFULED THE GROUND.
TOOT TO MANY WANT TO WATER.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH YOUR AND
RACHEL'S REMARKABLE STORY.
THANKS FOR BEING HERE.
UP NEXT.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT THE MENTAL
HEALTH OF THE SHOOTER.
STAY WITH US.
.
[ Male Announcer ]
WE ALL MAKE BAD DECISIONS.
LIKE SAY, GAS STATION SUSHI.
CHEAP IS GOOD.
AND SUSHI, GOOD.
BUT CHEAP SUSHI, NOT SO GOOD.
IT'S LIKE THAT SUPER-LOW RATE
ON NOT ENOUGH CAR INSURANCE.
PRETTY SKETCHY.
♪
AND THEN THERE ARE
THE GOOD DECISIONS.
LIKE ESURANCE.
THEIR COVERAGE COUNSELOR TOOL
HELPS YOU CHOOSE
THE RIGHT COVERAGE FOR YOU
AT A GREAT PRICE.
[ stomach growls ]
WITHOUT FEELING QUEASY.
THAT'S INSURANCE
FOR THE MODERN WORLD.
ESURANCE.
NOW BACKED BY ALLSTATE.
CLICK OR CALL.
'S LOT OF QUESTIONS REMAIN
ABOUT THE MENTAL HEALTH OF THE
SHOW.
DR. JULY WE ALWAYS HEAR AFTER
ONE OF THESE EVENTS THAT THERE
WERE SIGNS THAT THE PERSON WAS
GETTING OFF AND SIGNALS THAT
WE SHOULD HAVE BEEN ABLE TO
SEE .
WHAT ARE THOSE SIGNALS AND
SIGNS THAT WE OUGHT TO WATCH
FOR IN PEOPLE?
>> THE BEST PREDICTOR OF
VIOLENT BEHAVIOR IS THE
SYMPTOMS THAT A PERSON
DISPLAYED IN THE PAST.
AND IN A PROBLEM WITH
SITUATIONS LIKE THIS.
THEY ARE DIFFICULT TO PEG AND
YOU SEE PEOPLE GET WITH DRAWN.
IF YOU SEE A PERSON THAT YOU
KNOW AND LOVE AND CHANGING IN
THEIR BEHAVIOR.
AND GETTING WITH DRAWN AND
PERHAPS THEY ARE HAVING
EXTENDED PERIODS OF MOOD
DIFFICULTIES.
AND WHAT I OFTEN SEE IN FAMILY
MEMBERS AND FRIENDS OF THESE
PEOPLE, THEY WILL IGNORE THESE
THINGS OR GO BOO DENIAL ABOUT
THEM.
TYPICALLY WHEN PEOPLE ARE NOT
ACTING THE NORMAL WAY THAT
THEY BEHAVE, AND ARE TARTING
TO DISPLAY CERTAIN BEHAVIORS.
OF SUBTLE THINGINGS.
START -- WITH STRANGE BELIEFS
AND FIXATED ON THIPPINGS THAT
MAKE -- THINGS THAT MAKE THEM
ANGRY.
GETTING THEM INTO SEE SOMEONE
AND A PROFESSIONAL AND SEE IF
THIS IS IT A PASSING PHASE OR
IS THIS SOMETHING THAT IS A
TIP OF A ICEBERG.
A LOT OF THE ONOUS IS ON FRIND
FAMILY TO GET THEM TREATMENT.
THEY BRING POEM IN MY OFFICE
TO BE EVALUATED AND OTHER
TIMES, PEOPLE ARE IN DENIAL.
IF YOU HAVE A FRIEND OR FAMILY
NUMBER THAT NIDES TO BE
ASSESSED WE NEED TO GET THEM
IN THERE AND ACCEPT THE
DIAGNOSIS.
>> FAMILY MEMBERS ARE FEARFUL
TO TAKE ONE MUCH THEIR
CHILDREN TO SOMEONE LIKE YOU
AND SO AFRAID IT WILL CREATE
MORE PROBLEMS BOY MAKING THE
CHILD THINK THERE IS MANAGE
WRONG WITH HIM.
LET CHANGE. MOOD.
WHEN IS IT A MATTER OF HOW THE
CHILD MISANDING AND YOU HAVE
TO TAKE THAT RICK.
NTHE THAT OF EMPATHY IF A
PERSON IS CAPABLE OF HURTING
CHILDREN AND THINGS THAT
NOMOLLY AS A SOCIETY VALLEY
OUR INNOCENT AND PEL OUT.
WE CAN SEE IF WE TALK THE
ABOUT THE DISREGARD FOR RULES.
AND THE HIGH LEVEL OF
NARCECCIAN.
AND WE REQUESTEDED ISSUES OF
PARTIAL AND WHEN THE PERSON IS
IT NOT RECEIVING SOCIAL
INTERACTION AND PERSONAL
STRESSORS AND WE SHAKE IT UP
IT WILL EXPLODE A COKE CAN.
POEM IMPLODE.
AND MASS SHOOTERS THEY
EXEMPLOYED.
>> THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
NCOMING UP.
MAX LUICATO AND HELPING TO
COPE WITH AN EMOTIONOUS LOSS.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
.
♪
ON YOUR PREPAID CARD?
INTRODUCING CHASE LIQUID.
THE RELOADABLE CARD
WITH NO FEE RELOADS
AND WITHDRAWALS AT CHASE ATMS.
ALL FOR ONE FLAT MONTHLY FEE
SO THERE'S ZERO CONFUSION.
GET RID OF PREPAID PROBLEMS.
GET CHASE LIQUID.
MY DAUGHTER EMIL I WOULD BE
ONE OF THE FIRST TO GIVE HER
LOVE AND SUPPORT TO ALL OF
THOSES.
BECAUSE THAT IS THE TYPE OF
PERSON SHE IS.
NOT BECAUSE OF ANY PARENTING
THAT MY WIFE AND I COULD HAVE
DONE BUT BECAUSE THOSE WERE
THE GIFTS GIVEN TO HER BY HER
HEAVENLY FATHER.
>> MANY .
FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS AND
MEMBERS OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT ARE UNDOUBTEDLYING
THEMSELVES AND GOD ONE
QUESTION .
HOW DO WE HELP CONSOLE THOSE
GRIEVING FROM SUCH A LOSS.
JOINING ME FROM SAN ANTONIO,
TEXAS.
PASTOR MAX LUCADO .
I APPRECIATE YOU COMING TO
HELP AMERICA FIND HEALING.
27 VICTIMS AND A LOT OF PEOPLE
ARING WHY.
WHY DID GOD NOT ENTERVENE.
HE'S BIG ENOUGH TO DO IT AND
THAT IS IT A FAUR ENOUGH
QUESTION AND I AM SURE YOU
ARED THAT .
HOW DO YOU RESPOND.
>> IT IS IT A FAIR QUESTION
AND A QUESTION WE WREST WILL
WITH IF THERE IS IT A PICTURE
OF UNBRIDALED HORROR THIS IS
WHAT WE NEED TO KNOW .
WHAT HAPPENED FRIDAY, WAS A
PICTURE OF SOMEBODY VIOLATING
THE GREATEST GIFTS THAT GOD
GAVE HUMANITY AND THAT IS FREE
WILL.
99 PERCENT OF THE TIME THEY
US FREE WILL TO DO GOOD
THINGS AND CHOOSE TO LOVE AND
CHOOSE TO RESPECT.
THEY ARE CONSES AND
OPPORTUNITIES OF FREE WILL.
AND THIS IS IT A CASE AND I
SURE MENTAL ILWAS INVOLVED AND
I KNOW THE DEVIL WAS INVOLVED
AND A CASE WHERE THEY BUSED IT
IS IT AND THIS IS IT WHAT WE
HAVE TO BELIEVE.
GOD DID NOT CREATE THIS, BUT
GOD CAN USE AND TAKE THAT
WHICH WAS INTENDED FOR EVIL
AND TURN IT BOO SOMETHING
GOOD.
LIKE DARRYL ON YOUR BROADCAST
SHOWED US.
THE TERRIBLE DEATH FOR RACHEL
WAS USED FOR GOOD.
GOD REDEEMED SOMETHING.
I DON'T WANT TO SOUND LIKE A
BUMPER STICKER THEOLOGY.
THIS IS WHAT WE HAVE TO COME
BACK TO.
THE GOODNESS OF GOD AND HIS
OPPORTUNITY TO TURN EVIL TO
GOOD.
IS THAT IS IT AN IMPORTANT
POINT.
POEM ARE NOT SAYING IT IS IT A
GOOD THING.
I HEARD PEOPLE TRY TO CREATE
SELF INFLICTED JOY AND SAID
EVERYTHING IS GOD-- GOOD.
ALL THIPPINGINGS WORK TOGETHER
FOR GOOD .
BUT THIS IS IT NOT GOOD.
>> GOVERNOR, THIS STINKS .
THIS IS IT TERRIBLE.
THIS IS IT LIFE AT THE WORST
AND HUMANITY IN THE UGLIEST
AND THE UNDER BELLY OF THE
HUMAN SOUL AND THIS IS BAD.
WE NEED TO HATE IT WE NEED TO
HATE THAT WHICH IS EVIL.
WE NEED TO PRAY AGAINST IT AND
WORK AGAINST IT AND RAGE
AGAINST IT.
WE'LL GET THROUGH THIS.
BECAUSE ULTIMATELY GOD IS
STILL GOOD.
I THINK TWO OR THREE THIPPINGS
WE HAVE TO REMEMBER.
WE NEED TO PRAY OUR PAIN OUT.
IT IS NOT A TIME TO TURN AWAY.
BUT TURN TO GOOD.
FIPED THE COMMUPT TO HELP EACH
OTHER AND ENCOURAGE OTHERS TO
STRAY STRONG.
NTHE GOOD OF WHO AND WHAT GOOD
IS.
HE IS STRONG AND CAPABLE X.
FOCUS ON HEAVEN.
THERE IS NOTHING IN THE
BASEBALL SUGGEST WOULD THE
ABSEPS OF PAIN.
HIS LIFE WAS UNDERSTANDED ON A
CROSS.
AND GOD TOOK A SLAUGHTER OF
THE 99S AND CRUS FICTION OF
THE SAVOR AND TURNED IT NOTO
ACTS FOR THE SAVIOR.
THERE IS NOTHING GOOD BUT HE
WILL TURN IT IN TO SOMETHING
TO BE REDENTIVE.
NTHEIR KIDS SAW IT ON THE
TELEVISION AND READING AND
TALKING ABOUT.
HOW WOULD YOU RECOMMEPPED THAT
A PARENT SIT DOWN WITH A SON
OR DAUGHTER AND STAY YOU DON'T
HAVE TO BE AFRAID TO GO TO
SCHOOL THIS WILL NOT HAPPEN TO
YOU, MONOPOLIED.
>> THAT IS IT A GREAT
QUESTION, GOVERNOR.
I WOULD SAY THIS IS IT BAD .
THIS IS IT BAD.
WE LIVE IN A WORLD THERE IS
NOT JUST GOOD AND BAD.
BUT THERE IS IT BAD, THIS IS
IT REALLY BAD.
AND HELP OUR CHILDREN
UNDERSTAND THERE IS IT BAD IN
THE WORLD.
THERE IS A DEVIL AND A FORCE
OF EVIL.
AND HE'S NOT GOING TO WIN.
HIS TIME IS LIMITED AND HE'S
ON A SHORT LEASE.
OUR KIDS SEE EVIL EVERY DAY
AND WE NEED TO TELL THEP VILL
IS HERE.
WE ASSURE THEM WITH OUR LOVE
AND FECTION .
AND LET THIM SEE OUR TOURS AND
RECTION AND HONEST HOPE FOR
THEM.
WE DO OUR BEST TO CREATE
WITHIN.
AT A TIME LIKE THIS, THERE IS
NOODS OUT OF HEAVEN, OUTED OF
GOD.
WE HAVE TO TILL OUR KIDS.
WE WERE MILE FOR SOMETHING
DEFENSE.
NYOU GOD WILL BE VICK TOROUS.
MAY I ADD A WORD.
THERE MIGHT BE A YOUNG PERSON
WHO LOOKS TO THE PERSON IN
CONNECTICUT AS A YOUNG PERSON.
I WANT TO SAY TO
PERSON, THAT IS IT NOT THE
ANSWER.
THAT WILL NOT SOLD YOUR
PROBLEMS.
IF YOU EVER FINDING YOURSELF
LOOKING TO HIM WITH REQUEST
AND NOT DISGUST.
OPEN YOURSELF UP AND TALK TO
SOMEONE.
YOU DON'T WANT TO GO DOWN THE
ROAD.
HE'S NOT THE SOLUTION OR ROLE
MODEL.
MAY GOD HAVE MERCY ON YOU.
DON'T FOLLOW THE FAM EXAMPLE.
>> I CANNOT THRANK YOU ENOUGH
FOR BEING HERE TONIGHT.
I KNOW YOUR SCHEDULE IS
IMCREZIBLY BACK.
THARCHING YOU, LUCADO >> WE
ALL FEEL A SENSE OF GRIEF AND
PAIN.
AND SOMETIMES WE FEEL SO
INCREDIBLY HELPLESS .
AND YET WE CAN PRAY AND IT CAN
MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
>> IF I DIDN'T BELIEVE THAT, I
WOULD GIVE UP IN A FACE OF
SOMETHING AS HORRIBLEEEEE
>> AS WE LEAVE YOU TONIGHT, WE
WANT YOU TO SEE THE NAMES AND
AGES OF THOSE WHOSE LIVES WERE
ENDED BY THE TRAGEDY AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY.
THEIR AGES FROZEN IN DEATH BUT
HOPEFULLY NOT FORGOTTEN BY
THEIR FAMILIES, THEIR FRIENDS
AND THE REST OF AMERICA.
FROM NEW YORK, GOOD NIGHT.
♪