HOW BAD IT WAS AND PROBABLY
SOME EXPLANATION THAT LIES IN
WHATEVER ANGER HE HAD TOWARD
HIS MOTHER OR THE SCHOOL,
WHATEVER, THE PROBLEM WITH
THAT EXPLANATION, IT'S NOT
GOING TO EXPLAIN WHY ALL THESE
CHILDREN HAD TO BE KILLED AND
ANY MORE THAN THERE'S AN
EXPLANATION FOR SEPTEMBER
11TH, BUT IT DOESN'T EXPLAIN
WHY THE POOR GUY DELIVERING
BAGELS THAT DAY GOT KILLED FOR
WHATEVER THE CRAZY CAUSE WAS.
>> AND THE SAME WAY, THAT WAS
EXACTLY MY THOUGHT.
IT WAS SO UNFATHOMABLE ON THAT
DAY THAT SO MUCH HATRED COULD
DRIVE MEN TO HIJACK PLANES AND
DRIVE THEM INTO THE PENTAGON
AND SHANKSVILLE--
>> THERE'S A LOT TO THIS, JON.
I WAS WATCHING FOX EARLIER AND
HEARD GOVERNOR HUCKABEE TALK
ABOUT EVIL AND THE FACT THAT
SOMETIMES WE CAN'T CONFRONT
THE FACT, THERE'S JUST EVIL IN
THE WORLD.
WELL, THERE IS.
ON THE OTHER HAND, THERE ARE
ALSO MEDICAL AND SCIENTIFIC
CATEGORIES YOU CAN PUT THIS
INTO THAT THE FINAL RESULT IS
WE DON'T UNDERSTAND THIS WELL
ENOUGH AND ANYBODY OFFERING
SIMPLE SOLUTIONS TO SOMETHING
LIKE THIS IS OFFERING NO
SOLUTION.
THIS IS NOT A SIMPLE THING, IT
DOESN'T HAVE A SIMPLE
SOLUTION.
A LOT OF THINGS HAVE TO BE
LOOKED AT AS WE MOVE THROUGH
THIS BECAUSE WE'RE JUST NOT
GOOD AT PREDICTING THIS KIND
OF BEHAVIOR.
WE DON'T UNDERSTAND IT YET.
>> AT THE SAME TIME, THE WHOLE
NATION WANTS TO WRAP THIS
COMMUNITY IN A BIG HUG AND
JUST EMBRACE IT.
>> BECAUSE THE WHOLE NATION
REALIZES IT CAN HAPPEN TO
THEM.   IT COULD HAPPEN TO
NEWTON--
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, AN
IDYLLIC COMMUNITY, IT CAN
HAPPEN ANYWHERE IN THIS
COUNTRY.
IT DOESN'T MEAN IT'S GOING TO
HAPPEN, DOESN'T MEAN IT'S A
PREVALENT CRIME, IT ISN'T.
THIS IS NOT THE WAY MOST
CHILDREN, GOD FORBID ARE GOING
TO BE HURT OR INJURED.
OTHER WAYS TO GET HURT OR
INJURED AND WE HAVE TO PAY
ATTENTION TO.
THIS IS SO HORRIFIC AND SO
ARBITRARY IT COULD HAPPEN TO
ANY ONE OF US AND ALL OF US
HAVE THIS NIGHTMARE ABOUT OUR
CHILDREN AND THAT'S WHY I
THINK THIS WHOLE COUNTRY IS
TOGETHER ON THIS.
>> AND CERTAINLY THOSE PARENTS
ARE GOING TO BE SECOND
GUESSING LOTS OF DECISIONS.
>> I CAN'T IMAGINE, YOU KNOW.
>> AND THAT'S BEING A FATHER
AND I CAN'T IMAGINE HOW YOU --
I COULDN'T IMAGINE IT DURING
SEPTEMBER 11TH OR MANY OTHER
TIMES HOW YOU LIVE WITH IN,
HORRIBLE.
>> THOSE ANSWERS ARE YET TO
COME IN THE DAYS AHEAD.
WE ARE GOING TO CONTINUE OUR
CONVERSATION WITH MAYOR
GUILIANI IN JUST A BIT AND
CONTINUING COVERAGE OF THE
AFTERMATH OF THE TRAGEDY IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT JUST
AHEAD.
GET MARRIED,
HAVE A COUPLE OF KIDS,
[ children laughing ]
MOVE TO THE COUNTRY,
AND LIVE A LONG, HAPPY LIFE
TOGETHER
WHERE THEY ALMOST NEVER FIGHT
ABOUT MONEY.
[ dog barks ]
BECAUSE RIGHT AFTER
THEY GET MARRIED,
THEY'LL FIND
SOME RETIREMENT PEOPLE
WHO ARE PAID ON SALARY,
NOT COMMISSION.
THEY'LL GET
STRAIGHTFORWARD GUIDANCE
AND BE ABLE TO FOCUS ON OTHER
THINGS, LIKE EACH OTHER,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
>>  HI, EVERYBODY, THANK YOU
FOR JOINING US ON FOX NEWS ON
OUR SPECIAL COVERAGE THIS
SATURDAY OF THE MURDERS THAT
HAPPENED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
NEWTOWN, 60 MILES FROM NEW
YORK CITY, A COMMUTER TOWN IN
MANY WAYS, TO THE BIG CITY OF
MANHATTAN, BUT A COMMUNITY ALL
ITS OWN, A SMALL COMMUNITY
THAT MANY OF US PROBABLY
DIDN'T KNOW TOO MUCH ABOUT
YESTERDAY UNTIL WE GOT THE
NEWS OF THE SHOOTING AND
EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AT THIS POINT WE PROBABLY ALL
FEEL A LITTLE BIT CONNECTED TO
THIS COMMUNITY.
IT'S SOMETHING THAT THE
PRESIDENT TALKED ABOUT
YESTERDAY AND THE PRESIDENT
GETTING VERY EMOTIONAL WHILE
MAKING A STATEMENT AT THE
WHITE HOUSE SAYING WE'VE
ENDURED TOO MANY OF THESE
INCIDENTS OVER THE LAST FEW
YEARS AND EVERY TIME HE LEARNS
THE NEWS HE REACTS NOT AS A
PRESIDENT, BUT AS A PARENT.
LET'S LISTEN TO THE PRESIDENT.
>> I KNOW THERE'S NOT A PARENT
IN AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL
THE SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF
THAT I DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN, BEAUTIFUL
LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN THE AGES
AND FIVE AND TEN YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF GONE, AMONG
THE FALLEN WERE TEACHERS, MEN
AND WOMEN WHO DEVOTED THEIR
LIVES HELPING HOUR CHILDREN
FULFILL THEIR DREAMS, SO, OUR
HEARTS ARE BROKEN TODAY.
FOR THE PARENTS, AND
GRANDPARENTS, SISTERS AND
BROTHERS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN, AND FOR THE FAMILIES
OF THE ADULTS WHO WERE LOST.
>> THE PRESIDENT EMOTIONAL
YESTERDAY, SPEAKING ABOUT THE
SHOOTING.
THE PRESIDENT'S WEEKLY MEDIA
MESSAGE TODAY ALSO TOUCHING ON
THE SCHOOL MASSACRE AND THE
PRESIDENT SAYS THE COUNTRIES
HAS A HEART HEAVY WITH HURT
AND REPUBLICANS CANCELED THE
WEEKLY ADDRESS SAYING THEY
WANTED THE PRESIDENT TO SPEAK
FOR THE THE ENTIRE NATION AT
THIS TIME OF MOURNING.
JON?
>> WE JUST GOT A NOD OF ASCENT
FROM FORMER NEW YORK CITY
MAYOR RUDY GUILIANI.
THAT'S THE RIGHT THING TO DO.
>> ABSOLUTELY, I THINK THE
PRESIDENT SAID IT JUST
PERFECTLY AND MY HEART GOES
OUT TO HIM, NOW, I REMEMBER
SEPTEMBER 11TH RIGHT
AFTERWARDS HAVING TO DO TWO OR
THREE PRESS CONFERENCES AND
HARDEST THING TO DO WAS NOT TO
CRY AND I FOUND OUT THAT ONE
OF MY FRIEND'S WIFE HAD DIED
AND I ACTUALLY STOOD BEHIND
SOMEBODY SO NOBODY WOULD SEE
ME CRYING, BUT IT'S VERY, VERY
HARD TO NOT FEEL THE EMOTION
OF SOMETHING LIKE THIS, ALL OF
US BEING PARENTS AND EVEN ONES
THAT AREN'T PARENTS, THEY'RE
AUNTS OR UNCLES, THEY
UNDERSTAND CHILDREN AND
UNDERSTAND WHAT IT MEANS TO
HAVE THE INNOCENT LITTLE
CHILDREN JUST MOWED DOWN IN AN
ABSOLUTELY INCOMPREHENSIBLE
FACT AND HOW DOES SOMEBODY
STAND IN FRONT OF A CLASSROOM
AND KILL A FIVE OR
SIX-YEAR-OLD.
IT COMPLETELY IS IMPOSSIBLE
FOR ANY VAGUELY NORMAL PERSON
TO UNDERSTAND THAT.
>> AND THIS SCHOOL APPARENTLY
HAD DONE EVERYTHING RIGHT.
AISLE, YOU CANNOT, YOU
CANNOT--
EVEN IF THEY HAD TURNED THE
SCHOOL INTO A FORTRESS AND HAD
THE SCHOOLS LOCKED.
>> IN A COMMUNITY LIKE THAT,
THEY DID MORE IN A COMMUNITY
LIKE THAT THAN YOU WOULD
GENERALLY DO.
THIS IS A COMMUNITY WITH ONE
VIOLENT CRIME.
THIS ISN'T EVEN A DANGEROUS A
SUBURBAN OR URBAN AREA AND
THEY HAD MORE SECURITY THAN
ANY FACTS WOULD SUGGEST.
THE GUY BASICALLY SOUNDS LIKE
SHOT HIS WAY IN.
YOU COULD SAY, WELL, SHOULD
THEY HAVE HAD AN ARMED POLICE
OFFICER THERE?
NOTHING IN THE PAST SUGGESTED
THEY HAVE AN ARMED POLICE
OFFICER THERE.
HAVING AN ARMED POLICE OFFICER
IN THE SCHOOL IS SOMEWHAT
DISCONCERTING FOR THE CHILDREN
AND WHO IS TO SAY HE WOULDN'T
HAVE SHOT THE ARMED POLICE
OFFICER.
HE DID A PRETTY GOOD JOB OF
SHOOTING THE PRINCIPAL.
THIS KID LOOKS TWO THINGS
ABOUT HIM, LOOKS LIKE HE KNEW
HOW TO SHOOT, AND VERY GOOD
SHOOTING, HORRIFIC SHOOTING,
BUT GOOD SHOOTING IN A VERY
SHORT PERIOD OF TIME AND LOOKS
LIKE HE WAS JUST, VERY
DISTURBED, A SMART KID, A KID
WHO HAD AN INTELLECT.
>> THAT'S WHAT EVERYBODY SAID.
>> THAT'S A DANGEROUS KILLER.
>> HE WAS ALSO DESCRIBED AS A
GAMER.
>> DANGEROUS--
>> ONE IMMERSED IN SOME THE
VIDEO GAMES WHICH CAN BE
HORRIFICALLY VIOLENT AND I
THINK AS MUCH AS ANYTHING--
>> THIS IS A VERY DANGEROUS
KILLER WHEN YOU PUT ALL OF
THOSE ELEMENTS TOGETHER.
>> MAYOR GUILIANI, IT'S GOOD
TO HAVE YOU HERE TO SHARE YOUR
THOUGHTS AND CONSOLE THE
NATION IN THE SAME WAY AS
9/11.
>> THERE ARE A LOT OF THINGS
THAT CAN BE DONE ABOUT THIS.
THE ONLY THING IS, I URGE
DON'T FOCUS ON A SIMPLISTIC
SOLUTION, THIS IS NOT A
SIMPLISTIC PROBLEM, NOT SOLVED
EASILY.
>> FORMER MAYOR RUDY GUILIANI,
JENNA.
>> WE STRUGGLE WITH THE RIGHT
WORDS PAN A LOT OF US ARE
TRYING TO PUT WORDS TO THE
STORY AND I TELL THE VIEWERS
WHAT WE KNOW.
THIS IS THE MURDER OF OUR MOST
INNOCENT AND IT DESERVES THE
KIND OF RESPECT TODAY AS WE
CONTINUE TO LEARN MORE ABOUT
THE DEADLY SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
THIS TOWN, IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WE HAVE A LOOK BACK AT
YESTERDAY'S EVENTS AS THEY
UNFOLDED.
>> EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY
TODAY.
A CALL CAME IN TO DISPATCH AND
POLICE OF RACED TO THE SCHOOL.
>> THE CHILDREN OBVIOUSLY WERE
VERY SHAKEN, THEY WERE CRYING
IN THE CLOSET AND WHEN THEY
WERE LEVEL, POLICE MADE THEM
HOLD ON TO HANDS AND CLOSE
THEIR EYES.
>> THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM, BIRTHDAYS,
GRADUATIO
GRADUATIONS, WEDDINGS, KIDS OF
THEIR OWN.
>> THE GYM TEACHER DIRECTED US
TO STAY AGAINST THE WALL AND
EVERYBODY STARTED KIND OF
PANICKING.
>> THERE'S NO WORDS, IT'S
SHEER TERROR.
>> IT DOESN'T SEEM REAL, IT
JUST DOES NOT TEAM IT'S
POSSIBLE.
>> WE ALL HUDDLED AND I KEPT
HEARING THESE BOOMING NOISES.
>> I JUST ALL OF OUR MOMS ARE
NETWORKING, TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT WHAT'S GOING ON.
>> THE KIDS WERE TERRIFIED.
THEY WERE TERRIFIED.
THEY HAD JUST WITNESSED
SOMETHING AND THEY WERE, THEY
WERE TERRIFIED.
>> IT'S -- IT'S THE MOST I'VE
EVER BEEN TO.
>> MAY GOD BLESSED VICTIMS AND
IN THE WORDS OF THE
SCRIPTURES, FEEL THE BROKEN
HEARTED AND BIND UP THEIR
WOUNDS.
>> THE U.S. FLAG NOW FLYING AT
HALF STAFF ACROSS THE COUNTRY,
AND THE PRESIDENT HAS ORDERED
THE FLAGS TO BE LOWERED
THROUGH TUESDAY.
IT'S JUST ONE WAY THAT SO MANY
OF US ARE HONORING THOSE WHO
WERE MURDERED YESTERDAY.
WE'LL BE BACK IN JUST A MINUTE
AFTER A QUICK COMMERCIAL BREAK
FROM THE INFORMATION FROM THE
SCENE IN NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT,
ANSWERS OF WHY THIS ALL
HAPPENED WE CAN'T ANSWER
TODAY, BUT WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK
WITH MORE NEW ON FOX NEWS, THE
LATEST FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT AHEAD.
WITH SCOTTRADER
STREAMING QUOTES,
ANY WAY YOU WANT.
FULLY CUSTOMIZE IT
FOR YOUR TRADING PROCESS --
FROM THOUGHT TO TRADE,
ON EVERY SCREEN.
AND ALL IN REAL TIME.
WHICH MAKES IT JUST LIKE
HAVING YOUR OWN TRADING FLOOR,
RIGHT AT YOUR FINGERTIPS.
[ Rodger ] AT SCOTTRADE,
SEVEN DOLLAR TRADES
ARE JUST THE START.
TRY OUR
EASY-TO-USE
SCOTTRADER
STREAMING QUOTES.
IT'S ANOTHER REASON
MORE INVESTORS ARE SAYING...
[ All ]
I'M WITH SCOTTRADE.
IT'S ANOTHER REASON
MORE INVESTORS ARE SAYING...
Is bigger than we think ...
Sometimelike the flu.fer from
With aches, fever and chills-
the flu's a really big deal.
So why treat it like
it's a little cold?
There's something
that works differently
than over-the-counter
remedies.
Prescription TAMIFLU attacks
the flu virus at its source.
So don't wait. Call your
doctor right away.
TAMIFLU is prescription
medicine for treating the flu
in adults and children
one year and older
whose flu symptoms started
within the last two days.
Before taking TAMIFLU tell your
doctor if you're pregnant,
nursing. have serious
health conditions,
or take other medicines.
If you develop an allergic
reaction, a severe rash,
or signs of unusual behavior,
stop taking TAMIFLU and call
your doctor immediately.
Children and adolescents in
particular may be at an
increased risk
of seizures, confusion
or abnormal behavior.
The most common
side effects are
mild to moderate nausea
and vomiting.
The flu comes on fast,
so ask your
doctor about TAMIFLU.
Prescription for flu.
SINCE AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL
WAS FOUNDED BACK IN 1894,
THEY'VE BEEN COMMITTED
TO PUTTING CLIENTS FIRST.
HELPING GENERATIONS
THROUGH TOUGH TIMES.
GOOD TIMES.
NEVER TAKING A BAILOUT.
THERE WHEN YOU NEED THEM.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
OVER THE CENTURIES.
THE STRENGTH OF
A GLOBAL FINANCIAL LEADER.
THE HEART OF
A ONE-TO-ONE RELATIONSHIP.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
>>  THIS SCHOOL TRAGEDY
REVERBERATED THROUGHOUT THE
NATION, INCLUDING THE NATION'S
CAPITAL WHERE THERE'S BEEN AN
OUTPOURING OF GRIEF AS
LAWMAKERS REACT TO THE TRAGEDY
IN CONNECTICUT.
AM JAMES ROSEN LIVE IN D.C.
FOR US NOW.
>> Reporter:  JON, GOOD DAY TO
YOU.
WE ALL REMEMBER PRESIDENT
OBAMA'S POISED AND POIGNANT
PERFORMANCE AS THE CONSOLER IN
CHIEF AT THE MEMORIAL SERVICE
HELD AFTER THE TUCSON, ARIZONA
MASSAC
MASSACRE.
IN THE MAKE OF NEWTOWN,
MR. OBAMA FOUND IT DIFFICULT
TO KEEP HIS EMOTIONS IN CHECK.
HE APPEARED IN THE PRESS
BRIEFING ROOM NAMES AFTER
JAMES S BRADY, THE PRESS
SECRETARY WOUNDED IN THE
SHOOTING ATTACK ON PRESIDENT
REAGAN.
IN THE WEEKLY RADIO ADDRESS
THE PRESIDENT WAS A BIT MORE
COMPOSED.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES AND FIVE AND TEN
YEARS OLD.
MOST OF MOST WHO DIED WERE
JUST YOUNGHEIR
WHOLE LIVES AHEAD OF THEM.
EVERY PARENT IN AMERICA HAS
HAD A HEART HEAVY WITH HURT.
LOWERED TO HALF STAFF AT THE
WHITE HOUSE AND THE CAPITOL
BUILDING YESTERDAY HE.
THE NATION'S TOP LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS ATTORNEY
GENERAL ERIC HOLDER WAS IN
TULSA, OKLAHOMA YESTERDAY
HONORING THE NEW U.S. ATTORNEY
INSTALLED THERE.
>> I'M A FATHER OF THREE
CHILDREN MYSELF.
I CAN ONLY BEGIN TO IMAGINE
THE PAIN THAT THE PARENTS IN
CONNECTICUT ARE FEELING TODAY.
I WANT TO ASSURE THEM AND
PEOPLE IN THIS NATION WE'RE
DOING EVERYTHING WE CAN TO
INVESTIGATE THIS HORRENDOUS
CRIME AND OFFER ASSISTANCE ANY
WAY WE CAN AND THAT ALSO MEANS
WE ARE TELLING PEOPLE TO
CONNECTICUT TO DEAL WITH THE
TRAUMATIC IMPACT THAT THIS HAS
HAD.
>> Reporter:  HOUSE SPEAKER
JOHN BOEHNER ISSUED A CALL FOR
UNITY YESTERDAY, SAYING IN A
STATEMENT, LET US ALL CLING
TOGETHER IN GOD'S GRACE, TO
PRAY FOR THE FAMILIES OF THE
VICTIMS THAT THEY MAY FIND
COMFORT AND PEACE AMID SUCH
SUFFERING AND LET US GIVE
THANKS, BOEHNER ADDED, TO
THOSE WHO HELPED THEM GET TO
SAFETY.
AND NO PARENTS OF THE CHILDREN
MURDERED AT SANDY HOOK
DESCRIBED THE PAIN OF SUCH
TRAGEDY SAID HOUSE SPEAKER
NANCY PELOSI, NOBODY ALL
AMERICANS SHARE OUR PRAYERS
AND OUR GRIEF OVER THESE
HORRIFYING EVENTS AND EVERY
PERSON IS THRUST INTO THE
QUANDARY WITH THIS EVENT.
WE WANT TO TURN TO LANGUAGE
AND DISTINCTLY MAKE US HUMAN,
BUT WORDS FAIL US.
>> Jon: THANK YOU VERY MUCH,
JAMES ROSEN REPORTING FROM
D.C.
IN A SITUATION THAT INVOLVES
SO MUCH SADNESS AND HORROR,
THERE'S HEROISM TO DISCUSS,
WE'LL BE TALKING TO ONE OF THE
PEOPLE WHO WAS INSIDE AND
HELPED SAVE CHILDREN'S LIVES
COMING UP.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
IT STARTED LONG AGO.
THE JOY OF GIVING SOMETHING
EVERYTHING YOU'VE GOT.
IT TAKES PASSION.
AND IT'S NOT LETTING UP
ANYTIME SOON.
AT UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company,
WE UNDERSTAND THAT COMMITMENT.
AND ALWAYS HAVE.
SO DOES AARP,
AN ORGANIZATION
SERVING THE NEEDS
OF AMERICANS 50 AND OVER
FOR GENERATIONS.
SO IT'S NO SURPRISE
MILLIONS HAVE CHOSEN
AN AARP Medicare Supplement
Insurance Plan,
INSURED BY UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company.
LIKE ALL STANDARDIZED
MEDICARE SUPPLEMENT PLANS,
THEY HELP COVER
SOME OF THE EXPENSES
MEDICARE DOESN'T PAY.
AND SAVE YOU UP TO THOUSANDS
IN OUT-OF-POCKET COSTS.
TO FIND OUT MORE,
REQUEST YOUR
FREE DECISION GUIDE.
CALL OR GO ONLINE TODAY.
AFTER ALL,
WHEN YOU'RE GOING THE DISTANCE,
IT'S NICE TO HAVE
THE EXPERIENCE AND COMMITMENT
TO GO ALONG WITH YOU.
KEEP DREAMING. KEEP DOING.
GO LONG.
>> HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, JUST FIVE MINUTE
OR SO WALK TO THE SCHOOL
DIRECTLY THIS DIRECTION.
YOU CAN SEE THE COMMUNITY BALL
FIELD IS NOW A MEDIA STAGING
AREA.
AS FOLK FLOCK TO NEWTOWN TO
BETTER UNDERSTAND WHAT
HAPPENED YESTERDAY.
IT IS A RESIDENTIAL AREA AND
PEOPLE ARE WALKING ON THE
STREETS AND SO IT IS QUIET
TODAY.
A COUPLE WALKING EARLIER
A WOMAN ASK HER HUSBAND TALKED
TO US ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
YESTERDAY.
SHE IS A LIBRARY CLERK AND AT
THE SCHOOL YESTERDAY WHEN THE
SHOOTING HAPPENED.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> I TOLD THEM WHEN WE STARTED
ON THE INTERCOM THAT THEY WERE
GOING TO MAKE AN ANNOUNCE WE
HEARD SCUFFLING NOISE I
THOUGHT THEY WERE HITTING IT
BY MISTAKE AND ONE OF THE
SECRETARIES WORRIED ASK SAID
THERE IS A SHOOTING.
AND YOU KNOW, YOU BECOME AWARE
ASK WE HEARD THE GUN SHOTS AND
I YELLED LOCK DOWN AND TOLD
THE CLASSROOM LOCK DOWN.
>> YOU HAD TIME TO GO ASK TELL
THETH ARE THE CLASS.
>> IT IS JUST THE ONE ACROSS
THE HALL FROM ME .
>> KIDS WERE SCARED AND THEY
ARE SCARED EVEN WHEN IT IS A
DRILL .
THE FIRE ALARM GOES OFF IT IS
SCARY FOR LITTLE KIDS.
I DON'T THINK UNTIL WE OPENED
THE DOOR AND THERE WAS 15
STATE COPS WITH GUNS AND
AGENTS DID THEY REALLY --
>> WHAT WAS GOING THROUGH YOUR
MINDS WHAT THE CHILDREN WERE
SAYING.
NAND HOW LONG DID THAT TAKE.
>> THERE WAS NOT A GUNMAN
OUTSIDE OF THE DOOR.
WE WONT LET THEM IN.
AND THEY ARE POUNDING ON THE
DOOR SAYING THEY WERE POLICE
AND THEY HAD MACHINE CALL YUS
PUT A BADGE UNDER THE DOOR AND
WE REMOVED THE FILE CABINETS
AND LET THE KIDS OUT TO THEM.
MARY ANN JACOB A LIIAN CLERK
AT THE SCHOOL.
MORE FROM NEWTOWN AHEAD.