Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
THE PRESIDENT SAID WE CAN'T
TOLERATE THIS ANYMORE.
HE SAID WE CAN'T TOLERATE THIS
ANYMORE.
THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END, AND TO
SEE THEM END WE MUST CHANGE.
HE SPOKE ABOUT LAWS.
HE SAID NO SINGLE LAW, NO SET OF
LAWS WILL ELIMINATE EVIL FROM
THE WORLD BUT IF YOU CAN ACT TO
SAVE ONE LIFE TO PREVENT ONE
MORE ATTACK LIKE THIS, THAT'S
SOMETHING THE NATION MUST
ENGAGE.
SO HE IS SPEAKING TO AN AUDIENCE
THAT WANTS TO RECEIVE THE
MESSAGE, AND AN AUDIENCE OF
PEOPLE NOT JUST IN THE TOWN OF
NEWTOWN BUT ALL ACROSS THE
NATION THAT ARE HURTING.
>>Judge Jeanine:  I WAS THERE
LAST NIGHT, AND I HAVE TO TELL
YOU, WATCHING PEOPLE DOING KIND
OF MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS AND
LIGHTING CANDLES, IT WAS
PALPABLE.
YOU COULD FEEL THE PAIN AND
AGONY IN THAT TOWN.
I CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT IT'S LIKE
TODAY NOW THAT WE'RE FINALLY
DOING VIGILS AND PRAYER
SERVICES, AND TOMORROW THE FIRST
CHILD WILL BE BURIED.
>> YEAH.
AND THE ONLY WORD YOU CAN COME
UP WITH IS THAT IT'S SO SAD.
THE PEOPLE ARE BUILDING THE
MEMORIAL.
THEY'RE WEARING RIBBONS,
BRINGING THE TOYS.
THEY CREATED A LITTLE MEMORIAL
OF ANGELS, ONE REPRESENTING EACH
OF THE CHILDREN WHO WERE KILLED
IN THIS ACT.
BECAUSE NO ONE KNOWS WHAT THEY
CAN DO.
NO ONE REALLY BELIEVES THEY CAN
DO ANYTHING THAT WILL MAKE THE
SITUATION RIGHT.
BUT YOU HAVE TO DO SOMETHING AS
OPPOSED TO NOTHING.
BECAUSE PEOPLE ARE HURTING SO
BADLY, AND NO ONE HAS THE
ABILITY TO MAKE ANY SENSE OUT OF
WHAT HAPPENED HERE BECAUSE
SIMPLY IT JUST DOESN'T MAKE ANY
SENSE AT ALL, JUDGE.
>> MIKE TOBIN, THANKS SO MUCH.
NOW LET'S GO TO MOLLIE LYON WHO
HAS INFORMATION ON THE VICTIMS
AND THEIR FAMILIES.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT THE
VICTIMS?
>> JUDGE, AS THE NAMES HAVE COME
OUT, WE'RE FINALLY SEEING THEIR
FACES AND LEARNING A LITTLE MORE
ABOUT THEIR LIVES, ABOUT THE
LOVED ONES THAT ARE THEY'RE
LEAVING BEHIND.
LET'S START WITH SIX-YEAR-OLD
JACK PINTO.
A HUGE, HUGE GIANTS FAN.
THE FIRST-GRADER LOVED SPORTS
AND WAS HONORED BY HIS FAVORITE
TEAM AND FAVORITE PLAYER, VICTOR
CRUZ, WHO WROTE HIS NAME ON HIS
CLEATS.
ANOTHER FIRST-GRADER, JESSE
LEWIS, WAS SIX YEARS OLD.
HIS FATHER SAYS HE LOVED ANIMALS
AND RIDING HORSES.
OLIVIA ENGLE, ALSO SIX YEARS
OLD, ON A FACEBOOK MEMORIAL PAGE
CREATED BY FAMILY FRIENDS, SHE
IS PICTURED IN CHRISTMAS SCENE
PHOTOS.
AND THERE WERE SIX WOMEN KILLED
AS WELL.
THESE ARE TEACHERS,
ADMINISTRATORS, MANY OF THEM
REFERRED TO NOW AS HEROES,
INCLUDING VICTORIA SOTO, 27
YEARS OLD.
SHE URGED HER KIDS TO HIDE IN
HER CLASSROOM, FAMILY MEMBERS
SAY THEY WERE TOLD THAT SHE DIED
AFTER LYING TO THE SHOOTER,
AFTER TELLING THE SHOOTER SHE
HAD SENT THE KIDS TO THE GYM.
>> THANKS SO MUCH.
AND I'M JOINED NOW ON THE PHONE
BY CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE.
LIEUTENANT, I VERY MUCH
APPRECIATE YOUR JOINING US SO
SOON AFTER THE CEREMONY.
>> YES, MA'AM.
>> ALL RIGHT.
LIEUTENANT, TODAY MORE
INFORMATION CAME OUT, AND ONE OF
THINGS YOU TALK ABOUT IS THE
FACT IT APPEARS THERE'S A LOT
GOING ON IN SOCIAL MEDIA, AND
YOU WERE VERY CLEAR AT YOUR LAST
PRESS CONFERENCE THERE WILL BE
INVESTIGATIONS AND PROSECUTIONS
OF INDIVIDUALS WHO WERE SAYING
THAT THEY HAVE INFORMATION ON
THE CASE OR ARE POSING AS PEOPLE
WHO EITHER WERE PART OF THE
SHOOTING OR PART OF THE --
THREATENING INDIVIDUALS IN THIS
CASE.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT THAT?
>> IT'S VERY CLEAR, AS YOU HAVE
BEEN REPORTING AND SPEAKING
ABOUT, A VERY COMPLEX
INVESTIGATION.
IT'S A VERY DIFFICULT
AND THERE IS A GREAT DEAL OF
INNUENDO AND INCORRECT
INFORMATION THAT'S BEING PUT OUT
THERE BY PEOPLE WHO ARE POSING
AS OFFICIALS, WHO ARE POSING AS
PEOPLE THAT THEY ARE NOT, AND
THEY ARE SIMPLY CAUSING
INTERFERENCE IN THE
INVESTIGATION.
WE CERTAINLY ARE FOLLOWING EVERY
SINGLE LEAD AND TIDBIT OF
INFORMATION WE UNCOVER, LEAVING
NO STONE UNTURNED AND THIS IS
ACTUALLY HINDERING THE
INVESTIGATION.
SO I HAVE SPOKEN WITH THE
FEDERAL AUTHORITIES AND THEY'RE
RIGHT ONBOARD, AND IN FACT IF
THERE ARE ANY -- ANYONE POSTS
ANYTHING THAT IS INCORRECT,
INACCURATE OR THREATENING, THEY
WILL BE THOROUGHLY INVESTIGATED
AND PROSECUTED THE FULLEST
EXTENT OF THE LAW.
>> LIEUTENANT, YOU INDICATED
THERE WAS A FOURTH WEAPON THAT
WAS FOUND IN THE SHOOTER'S CAR,
THE SUSPECT'S CAR, ADAM LANZA'S
CAR -- I HATE SAYING HIS NAME
AND I'M GOING TO TRY NOT TO.
BUT WE KNOW THAT HE TOOK THE
LONG GUN, THE BUSHMASTER, AS
WELL AS THE GLOCK AND THE SIG
SAUE.
THE FOURTH GUN THAT YOU
INDICATED WAS THERE, WHAT KIND
OF A GUN WAS THAT?
>> THAT WAS A SHOTGUN THAT WAS
LOCATED BY INVESTIGATORS AFTER
THE SHOOTING, INSIDE OF THE
SUSPECT'S CAR.
>> WE BELIEVE THAT WAS SOMETHING
THAT HIS MOTHER -- THAT WAS
ANOTHER GUN THAT BELONGED TO HIS
MOTHER?
>> THE OWNERSHIP IS
UNDETERMINED.
I'M NOT PRIVY TO THAT
INFORMATION.
SUFFICE TO SAY ALL OF THE
WEAPONS ARE BEING INVESTIGATED
THOROUGHLY BY A TEAM FROM THE
DAY THEY WERE BUILT, UP TO THE
DAY WE SEIZED THEM, TRYING TO
DETERMINE EVERY AVENUE THOSE
WEAPONS TOOK, WHERE THEY WERE
USED, WHO THEY WERE USED BY, AND
EVERYTHING ASSOCIATED WITH THEM.
>> YOU KNOW, LIEUTENANT, NOW WE
HAVE THE TECHNOLOGY AND THE
ABILITY TO DO WHAT IS CALLED
BALLISTIC FINGERPRINTS, WHERE,
AS YOU SAY, WE GO BACK TO
ACTUALLY THE MAKING OF THE GUN
AND THE -- THERE WERE 30
MAGAZINE -- 30 CLIP MAGAZINES
HERE, AS WELL AS FINDING OUT
WHERE THIS GUN MAY HAVE BEEN
USED OR ANY OF THE GUNS MAY HAVE
BEEN USED IN THE PAST.
IT'S REALLY A HISTORY OF EACH OF
THE WEAPONS.
>> THAT'S VERY CORRECT.
AND WE SEIZED NUMEROUS CLIPS
THAT WERE FOR THE AR-15.
WE SEIZED NUMEROUS CLIPS FOR THE
SEMI AUTOMATIC HANDGUN, AND WE
WILL INVESTIGATE THE ORIGIN OF
EVERY PIECE OF WEAPONRY UTILIZED
THIS IN TRAGEDY.
>> LIEUTENANT, THERE ARE REPORTS
THAT AS A YOUNG BOY THE SHOOTER
HAD GONE WITH HIS MOTHER TO GUN
RANGES.
HAVE YOU BEEN ABLE TO CONFIRM
THAT?
>> I AM NOT AWARE OF THAT
INFORMATION.
BUT, AGAIN, ALL OF THAT WILL BE
EXAMINED.
EVERY SIGNIFICANT PIECE OF
INFORMATION RELATIVE TO WEAPONS,
THEED INDICATION, LICENSURE,
REGISTRATION, EVERYTHING.
>> I HAVE NO DOUBT, HAVING
LISTENED TO YOU FOR THE PAST
SEVERAL DAYS, AND I BELIEVE
TODAY, THE LAST TWO APSIS WERE
DONE.
CLEARLY THE SHOOTER KILLED
HIMSELF, INTERESTINGLY, REPORTS
ARE HE USED A HANDGUN, WHEREAS
HE USED THE BUSH MASTER ON THE
CHILDREN AND TEACHERS.
IS THAT CORRECT?
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
>> AND THAT THE MOTHER-ACCORDING
TO REPORTS, WAS SHOT IN THE FACE
AND ACTUALLY SHOT FOUR TIMES IN
HER BADGE JAM -- PAJAMAS AND HER
BED.
>> THE PLACE OF DEATH I AM NOT
FAMILIAR WITH BUT THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER INDICATED SHE DIED OF
MULTIPLE GUNSHOT WOUNDS.
>> LIEUTENANT, LET ME ASK YOU, A
SOMEWHERE PERSONAL QUESTION.
AS A PROSECUTOR AND A JUDGE FOR
30 YEARS, HOW ARE YOU DOING?
>> WE'RE FINE.
YOU KNOW, THIS IS THE -- AS YOU
CERTAINLY CAN IMAGINE, ONE OF
THE MOST HEARTBREAK HORRIFIC
CRIME SCENES MANY OF US HAVE
EXPERIENCED.
WE HAVE TO WORK THROUGH THAT.
THE MEN AND WOMEN ARE GETTING
SUPPORT FROM CERTAINLY SOCIAL
SERVICE AGENCIES AND EMPLOYEE
ASSISTANCE AS REQUIRED, BUT WE
HAVE TO RAISE UP TO THE
CHALLENGE, AND WE'RE GOING TO DO
EVERYTHING HUMANLY POSSIBLE TO
ANSWER ALL THE QUESTIONS
SURROUNDING WHY AND HOW THIS
OCCURRED.
>> WELL, OF THAT I HAVE NO
DOUBT.
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANS, YOU HAVE
BEEN DOING A TERRIFIC JOB.
THANKS SO MUCH FOR JOINING US.
>> THANK YOU, YOUR HONOR.
>> COMING UP IN A FOX NEWS
EXCLUSIVE, A MAN WHO KNEW THE
SHOOTER AND HIS MOTHER AND
SENSED SOMETHING WAS NOT RIGHT.
[ HEART BEATING,
MONITOR BEEPING ]
Woman: WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
HOMEOWNERS INSURANCE
DOESN'T COVER FLOODS?
[ HEART RATE INCREASES ]
Man: A FEW INCHES OF WATER
CAUSED ALL THIS?
[ HEART RATE INCREASES ]
Woman #2: BUT I DON'T EVEN LIVE
NEAR THE WATER.
WHAT YOU DON'T KNOW ABOUT FLOOD
INSURANCE MAY SHOCK YOU --
INCLUDING THE FACT
THAT A PREFERRED RISK POLICY
STARTS AS LOW AS $129 A YEAR.
FOR AN AGENT, CALL THE NUMBER
THAT APPEARS ON YOUR SCREEN.
>> YOU WERE THE DIRECTOR OF
SECURITY FOR THE BOARD OF
EDUCATION WHICH INCLUDED A HIGH
SCHOOL WHERE THE SHOOTER
ATTENDED AS WELL AS PART OF THE
SAME SCHOOL DISTRICT WHERE THESE
CHILDREN, THESE INNOCENT
CHILDREN WERE MURDERED ALONG
WITH MANY OF THEIR TEACHERS.
>> YES.
>> AS DIRECTOR OF SECURITY YOU
HAD OCCASION TO MEET AND
INTERACT WITH MANY STUDENTS.
>> YES, MOST OF THEM.
>> AND YOU DID MEET I BELIEVE
SEVERAL YEARS AGO THE SHOOTER IN
THIS CASE ADAM LANZA.
WHAT WERE YOUR IMPRESSIONS OF
HIM?
>> I BELIEVE I FIRST MET HIM
+G:Ry![8+Oe-6]>L[d34<Xs<;#çlaH.
HE WAS A YOUNG MAN NOT UNLIKE
OTHER YOUNG MEN BUT WITH A FEW
DISORDERS THAT HAD TO BE
ADDRESSED.
>> WHAT KIND OF DISORDERS?
>> ASBURGERS IS OUT THERE.
HE WAS WITHDRAWN AND HAD
DIFFICULTY INTERACTING WITH
OTHER STUDENTS.
>> RICHARD, WHEN YOU SAY
ASBERGERS IS OUT THERE, DID YOU
KNOW THAT AT THE TIME?
HOW OLD WAS HE WHEN YOU FIRST
MET HIM?
DO YOU REMEMBER?
>> 13SHGS 14 YB÷çoXGQ!F,PWXv(ÑAf
SCHOOL.
bEçeg(ST39S Js88L;ç;EaUxPw:
FRESHMAN YEAR HE WAS Y
SMALL IN SIZE AND HE HAD A LOT
OF FEAR COMING INTO THE HIGH
SCHOOL AND INTERACTING WITH
OTHER STUDENTS.
>> BUT DID HE HAVE A REASON TO
BE FEARFUL OF THE OTHER
STUDENTS?
WAS HE PICKED ON?
>> NOT REALLY, NO.
NO.
NOT REALLY.
NEWTOWN SYSTEM ITSELF IS A VERY,
VERY LOVING CARING SCHOOL.
THE ADMINISTRATORS, THE
TEACHERS, MOST OF THE STUDENTS
USUALLY ADOPT KIDS YOUNGER THAN
THEM.
NO, THERE WASN'T.
>> ALL RIGHT.
RICHARD DID YOU HAVE OCCASION TO
MEET HIS MOTHER DURING THE TIME
THAT HE WAS IN SCHOOL, NANCY
LANZA?
>> YES, OFTEN.
>> TELL US ABOUT HER.
>> SHE WAS A GREAT PERSON.
I LIKED HER VERY, VERY MUCH.
SHE WAS THE TYPE OF PARENT WHO
INTERACTED WITH HER CHILDREN,
WAS DEEPLY INVOLVED IN THE
EDUCATIONAL PROCESS.
FRIENDS WERE PROBABLY CHOSEN
WELL.
THE ACTIVITIES SHE WAS INVOLVED
IN ALL OF THE TIME.
>> HOW DID SEE AHE AND HER SON
INTERACT?
>> TOUGH TO SAY.
QUITE WELL.
THERE WAS A DIFFERENCE BETWEEN
TWOT BOYS.
ONE WAS OUT GOING AND  ENERGETI
ADAM WAS WITHDRAWN AND SHY.
THE IDEA WAS TO INJECT HIM INTO
AN ENVIRONMENT WHERE HE WOULD
THRIVE AND MAYBE GROW AND COME
OUT OF HIS WORLD.
>> WERE YOU SURPRISED WHEN YOU
HEARD ALL OF THIS?
>> SHOCKED.
I AM STILL SHOCKED.
>> WHY?
>> THIS IS A BOY WHO WAS MORE
LIKELY A VICTIM WHICH IS WHY I
WOULD WATCH HIM VERY CLOSELY
RATHER THAN BE THE PERSON WHO
VICTIMIZED.
I AM SHOCKED.
>> FRIDAY MORNING JUST BLEW ME
AWAY.
I WAS BUSY WITH WORK AND I FIST
RECEIVED A TEXT FROM MY OWN SON
WHO ATTENDED THE SCHOOL SYSTEMS.
I REALLY I DO BELIEVE THIS COULD
BE POSSIBLE.
>> ARE YOU SURPRISED THE MOM HAD
SO MANY GUNS?
>> I AM SHOCKED.
I AM SURPRISED SHE HAD THAT MANY
GUNS.
CAUSED ME TO REALLY RETHINK
KEEPING ME UP AT NIGHT WONDERING
WHY I WOULD NOT HAVE ENVISIONED
HER NOT ONLY TO HAVE GUNS BUT
THE TYPE OF GUNS.
>> WE THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
SHARING YOUR INSIGHT ON THE
SHOOTER AND HIS MOTHER.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US THIS
EVENING.
>> THANK YOU, JUDGE.
>> COMING UP TOMORROW MORNING
MILLIONS OF CHILDREN WILL GO
BACK TO SCHOOL.
WILL THEY EVEN BE SAFE?
CAN SOMETHING LIKE THIS HAPPEN
AGAIN?
LATER THEY SAY TIME HEALS ALL
WOUNDS, BUT HOW LONG WILL IT
TAKE TO HEAL AFTER A TRAGEDY
LIKE THIS.
LOTS OF PREPAID CARDS COME
PRE-FILLED WITH PROBLEMS.
ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
INTRODUCING CHASE LIQUID.
THE RELOADABLE CARD
WITH NO-FEE RELOADS
AND WITHDRAWALS AT CHASE ATMS.
AND NO HEADACHES,
HASSLES OR CONFUSION.
ALL FOR ONE FLAT MONTHLY FEE.
GET RID OF PREPAID PROBLEMS.
GET CHASE LIQUID.
(INAUDIBLE)
>> TOMORROW MORNING MILLIONS OF
CHILDREN ACROSS AMERICA HEAD
BACK TO SCHOOL.
THEIR PARENTS ARE NOW FORCED TO
WONDER, IS MY CHILD SAFE?
WITH ME IS FORMER NYPD DETECTIVE
AND SCHOOL SAFETY EXPERT.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US,
HARRY.
WE KNOW THE SANDY HOOK SCHOOL
SYSTEM THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
PARTICULAR HAD MEASURES IN PLACE
FOR SAFETY, AND IT IS OBVIOUS TO
STOP THIS CRAZED INDIVIDUAL.
HE IS EVIL.
HE DID THE DEVIL'S WORK.
WHAT CAN WE DO IN SCHOOLS TO
PROTECT OUR CHILDREN?
>> THEY DID HAVE SOME PLAN IN
THE SCHOOL.
WE COULD PROBABLY TWEAK THAT,
THOUGH.
>> HOW?
>> APPARENTLY THE SHOOTER GOT IN
THROUGH THE GLASS DOOR.
WHAT HAPPENS IS HE SHOT THE
GLASS DOOR OUT AND WENT INSIDE.
THE CLASS ITSELF WASN'T -- WAS
VERY EASILY PENETRATED.
HE WAS ABLE TO ACCESS THE
SCHOOL.
SO THERE'S A COUPLE DIFFERENT
THINGS WE CAN DO.
>> WHAT?
>> SOMETHING SIMPLE LIKE PUT THE
BARS ON THE DOORS.
>> PEOPLE SAY, HARRY THAT THAT'S
INTIMIDATING.
YOU DON'T WANT METAL DETECTORS
YOU DON'T WANT A COP WITH A GUN.
NOW YOU ARE TALKING BARS.
YOU BELIEVE THIS IS SOMETHING WE
NEED TO DO?
>> I THINK THAT THE LOCK DOWN IS
PROBABLY THE ANSWER.
>> DESCRIBE A LOCK DOWN.
>> YOU DO WITH YOUR EMERGENCY
ACTION PLAN.
IT IS BASICALLY LOCKING DOWN THE
SCHOOL WHICH THEY TRIED TO DO.
THEY LOCKED ALL OF THE DOORS.
>> BUT THE SHOOTER IS IN THE
SCHOOL.
RIGHT, EXACTLY.
THE SHOOTER GOT INTO THE SCHOOL.
IF THEY HAD SOME KIND OF BARS ON
THAT DOOR MAYBE THE SHOOTER
COULD NOT HAVE GOTTEN TO THE
SCHOOL.
>> SO LET'S ACCOUPLE THAT THERE
IS THIS AS YOU CALL SAFETY OR
EMERGENCY ACTION PLAN.
THAT MEANS THAT WE HAVE TO TRAIN
THE TEACHERS AND EFSHL ELSE.
IS THIS EXPENSIVE?
WHO PAYS FOR IT IN A WORLD WHERE
THE END OF THE FISCAL CLIFF, HOW
DIFFICULT IS IT?
>> WE KNOW THAT SCHOOLS AREN'T
GOING TO PUT 50,000 DOLLARS INTO
A SECURITY UPGRADE.
SOMETHING LIKE THIS IS EASY TO
DO.
IT IS A LITTLE SCHOOLING.
YOU CAN BASICALLY GET A HANDYMAN
TO DO SOME OF THE WORK TO THE
WINDOWS AND TO THE DOORS AND YOU
WILL HAVE A HE CSECURE SCHOOL.
WHAT WE NEED TO DO IS HAVE SOME
TYPE OF AN ALARM WHERE THEY KNOW
IT IS TIME FOR THE LOCK DOWN.
>> EVERYBODY HEARD WHAT WAS
GOING ON.
>> WHAT SHOULD PARENTS DO
TOMORROW MORNING SHOULD THEY
CALL THEIR SCHOOL AND SAY HEY
WHAT IS THE SAFETY PLAN FOR MY
CHILD?
>> THAT IS SOMETHING THEY SHOULD
DEFINITELY DO.
I SUGGEST PARENTS CALL THE
SCHOOL AND ASK THEM DO YOU HAVE
AN EMERGENCY ACTION PLAN IN
EFFECT IN THE SCHOOL?
IF NOT, WHY?
AND IF NOT, WHEN?
GET TOGETHER WITH THE PTA, THEN
YOU CAN ALL GET TOGETHER TALK
WITH THE SCHOOL OFF FIFSH SHALLS
AND POLICE AND PUT AN EMERGENCY
ACTION PLAN TOGETHER.
LOCK DOWN IS VERY COST
EFFECTIVE.
>> WHAT ABOUT CHILDREN?
WHEN YOU SAY THAT WE HEARD ABOUT
THE DRILLS THESE CHILDREN
BEFORE, I USE TO DO HIDE UNDER
THE DESK.
MY KIDS WILL SAY THAT'S WHERE
THEY WERE WRITTEN ON THE SILK
TABLETS.
TODAY THE DRILL IS WHAT?
SIMPLY TO GO OUT OF THE SCHOOL?
HOW DO YOU PREPARE LITTLE KIDS
WITHOUT SCARING THEM?
>> FOR AN ACTIVE SHOOTER YOU
DON'T WANT THE KIDS RUNNING OUT
OF SCHOOL.
THEY CAN RUN INTO THE ACTIVE
SHOOTER.
YOU WANT TO BE ABLE TO LOCK DOWN
THE CLASSROOM.
IF YOU CAN LOCK DOWN THE
CLASSROOM, GET THE CHILDREN DOWN
ON THE FLOOR, TAKE THEIR DESKS
LAY THEM OVER GET BEHIND THE
DESKS LOCK THE DOOR SO THE
SHOOTER DOESN'T GAIN ACCESS TO
THAT.
THE FIRST TWO OR THREE MINUTES
OF AN ACTIVE SHOOTER INCIDENT IS
THE DEADLIEST.
WHAT WE WANT TO DO IS WE WANT TO
SLOW HIM DOWN SO THAT IF WE SLOW
HIM DOWN THE POLICE CAN RESPOND
AND THEN THE POLICE CAN DEAL
WITH HIM.
>> VERY QUICKLY, YOU WERE A
DETECTIVE, HOMICIDE DETECTIVE AT
NYPD.
THESE GUNS WE WERE HEARING ABOUT
THE GLOCH THE BUSHMASTER A LOT
OF VIEWERS DON'T KNOW WHAT THEY
ARE CAPABLE OF.
A SEMIAUTOMATIC THEY ARE TALKING
ABOUT 30 ROUNDS TO A CLIP.
HOW QUICKLY CAN THAT GO OFF?
>> YOU HAVE THE BUSHMASTER.
>> WHICH IS RIGHT ON THE SCREEN
RIGHT THERE.
>> YOU HAVE THE 223 OR 2.56
ROUND MILITARY ROUND.
YOU CAN EMPTY A 30 ROUND CLIP IN
LESS THAN 15 SECONDS IF YOU ARE
REALLY TRAINED TO DO THAT.
>> THAT IS SCARY.
>> THEY SAID THERE WERE HUNDREDS
OF ROUNDS.
OBVIOUSLY 30 ROUND CLIP HUNDREDS
OF ROUNDS THAT MEANS HE WAS
RELOADING.
>> IN ALL CASES THIS QUICK, BAM,
BAM.
>> APPRECIATE IT.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR EXPERTISE.
DO WE SPEND TOO MUCH TIME TRYING
TO UNDERSTAND WHAT TO ME IS
SIMPLY AND PURELY EVIL?
AND LATER, DOES FAITH, RELIGION
AND BELIEF IN GOD HOLD A KEY TO
HEALING?
>> OTHER STORIES WE ARE
FOLLOWING.
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON RECOVERING AT HOME AFTER
FAINTING AND SUFFERING A
CONCUSSION.
SHE WAS SCHEDULED TO TESTIFY AT
HEARINGS LOOKING INTO THE
BENGHAZI EVENTS.
SENIOR STATE DEPARTMENT
OFFICIALS WITH TESTIFY IN HER
PLACE.
>> GROWING MISERY IN THE FILL
MEANS AS THE DEATH TOLL HAS
GROWN TO 1,000 FROM A TYPHOON.
A MASSIVE SEARCH FOR 844 PEOPLE
STILL MISSING.
IT'S SET TO CONTINUE INTO THE
NEW YEAR.
ARMY TROOPS, POLICE, AND
GOVERNMENT PERSONNEL CANCELING
CHRISTMAS CELEBRATIONS IN ORDER
TO HELP.
ALL YOUR LATEST HEADLINES, LOG
ON TO FOXNEWS.com.
YOU'RE WATCHING THE MOST
POWERFUL NAME IN NEWS, FOX NEWS
CHANNEL.
JANEANE FROM NEWTOWN
CONNECTICUT.
>> THE PERSON THAT CHOOSE TO ACT
THIS WAY WAS ACTING WITH A GOD
GIVEN RIGHT HE WAS GIVEN BY GOD
THAT HAS GIVEN ALL OF US TO ACT
AND CHOOSE WHATEVER WE WANT.
GOD CAN'T TAKE THAT AWAY FROM
US.
>> THE TOWN STRUGGLES TO COME TO
GRIPS WITH THE UNIMAGINABLE.
THE QUESTION REALLY IS HOW WILL
WE EVEN BEGIN TO HEAL.
WITH ME CLINICAL PSYCHOLOGIST
AUTHOR OF INSIDE THE CRIMINAL
MIND AND PSYCHOLOGIST DR. ROBY
LUDWIG.
>> YOU SAW THAT IT IS
HEARTBREAKING THE FATHER OF A
6-YEAR-OLD THWHO BASICALLY FOR
GIVES HE IS NOT ANGRY.
HOW DOES A PARENTS DO THAT?
>> HE WASNHASN'T GOTTEN IN TOUC
WITH HIS ANGER.
IT IS SOMETHING HE WILL HAVE TO
DEAL WITH.
HIS WHOLE LIFE WAS TURNED UPSIDE
DOWN.
HIS DAUGHTER'S LIFE WAS ROBBED
FROM HER.
O
SO OF COURSE THERE'S ANGER.
THERE'S A HEALTHY COMPONENT.
IF YOU GET STUCK IN THE ANGER
THAT IS WHEN IT IS NOT HEALTHY.
YOU CAN HEAR THE FATHER'S
INSTINCTS ARE REALLY GOOD.
HE'S KEEPING HIS DAUGHTER'S
MEMORY ALIVE MAKING THE MEMORY
VIVID FOR THE WHOLE WORLD TO
EXPERIENCE.
THAT'S THE FIRST HEALTHY STEP
MANY OF THE PARENTS ARE GOING TO
NEED TO DO.
>> WHEN I WAS READING ABOUT THE
CHILDREN, THERE IS ONE OF THE
CHILDREN NOAH WHO IS GOING TO BE
BURIED TOMORROW.
HE HAS A TWIN SIBLING.
SHE WAS IN ANOTHER CLASSROOM.
HOW DOES SHE AT THIS YOUNG AGE,
SHE WON'T REALLY COMPLETELY
UNDERSTAND IT, BUT AT SOME POINT
WILL SHE HAVE WHAT'S CALLED
SURVIVOR'S GUILT?
>> WE DON'T HAVE THE ANSWERS TO
EVERYTHING THAT HAPPENS IN LIFE.
WE DON'T KNOW WHY CHILDRERTAIN E
SURVIVE AND CERTAIN PEOPLE
DON'T.
PERHAPS HER ROLE CAN BE IN
TRYING TO MAKE THIS A POSITIVE
FOR HERSELF.
GIVE HER BROTHER'S LIFE SOME
MEANING.
WHO KNOWS, MAYBE SHE WILL END UP
BEING A DEFENSE ATTORNEY ONE
DAY.
>> MAYBE A PROSECUTOR.
>> I TACHANGE MY STATEMENT.
>> DOCTOR, YOU ARE VERY FAMILIAR
WITH THE CRIMINAL ELEMENTS WHO
BASICALLY REFUSES TO BE CAUGHT
IN A TRAP OF LABELLING THESE
PEOPLE WHO ARE KILLING UNDER THE
GOOIDZ OF A MENTAL ILLNESS.
>> THE TALK ABOUT AUTISM AND THE
SHOOTER LACKING SOCIAL SKILLS.
DO YOU REALIZE EVERY ONE OF
THESE SHOOTERS HAS BEEN
DESCRIBED AS A LOANER AND WITH
DRAWN.
YOU KNOW WHY THAT IS?
BECAUSE THESE ARE PEOPLE WHO
DON'T WANT OTHERS TO KNOW THEM.
THESE ARE PEOPLE WHO ARE
SECRETIVE.
THESE ARE PEOPLE WHO HAVE A LOT
GOING ON IN THEIR MINDS THAT
THEY WILL NOT ANNOUNCE TO
OTHERS.
THEY SIMPLY DON'T HAVE SOCIAL
SKILLS BECAUSE THEY DON'T CARE
ABOUT SOCIAL SKILLS.
THEIR VIEW OF LIFE IS THEY ARE
THE HUB OF THE WHEEL EVERYTHING
MUST REVOLVE AROUND IT.
WE PUT LABELS ON TRYING TO
EXPLAIN THE UNEXPLAINABLE AND
THERE BY CREATE MORE EXCUSES.
>> DOCTOR AS SOMEONE WHO TRIED A
LOT OF CRIMINAL CASES MURDER
CHASES INSANITY DEFENSES I NEVER
THOUGHT THE ISSUE OF INSANITY
WHICH PEOPLE WILL SURELY COME
UPON IN THE NEAR FUTURE AS IT
RELATES TO THIS CASE HAS
ANYTHING TO DO WITH THE FACT OF
WHAT WAS DONE.
AND SO THE LABELLING OF
ASPERGER'S WHICH I HAVE SEEN IT
USED IN OTHER HOMICIDE CASES IS
ALMOST AN EXCUSE.
PEOPLE SAY OH BUT HE WAS SMART.
THAT'S ALMOST AN EXCUSE AS WELL.
>> THE FACT THAT THE PERPETRATOR
WAS SMART MAKES FOR A WONDER RL
COVER.
IF YOU ARE SMART, A BRAINIAC I
BELIEVE HE WAS CALLED THAT MAKES
IT EASIER TO GET A PASS FOR
OTHERS TO FOCUS ON HOW BRIGHT
THE PERSON IS.
THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO SAID TO ME
TO KILL SOMEBODY YOU HAVE TO BE
INSANE.
YOU HAVE TO LOOK AT THE FACTS OF
THE CASE.
HOW THE SHOOTINGS WERE COMMITTED
HOW PURPOSEFUL, HOW RATIONAL AND
DELIBERATE BRAT THEY WERE.
>> SPINNING OFF OF IT YOU HAVE A
GUY WHO SHOOTS HIS OWN MOTHER IN
THE FACE, SHOOTS HER FOUR TIMES.
WHAT IS HE SO ANGRY ABOUT?
>> WE DON'T KNOW.
BUT CLEARLY THERE WAS A
CONTENTIOUS RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN
HIM AND HIS MOTHER.
>> WE HEARD ABOUT FROM THE
TEACHER, I BELIEVE FOUR YEARS
BACK MAYBE THREE YEARS BACK IS
THE MOTHER CARED ABOUT HIM AND
CARED ABOUT HIM.
>> SHE MAY HAVE.
INTERPERSONAL RELATIONSHIPS
BETWEEN A MOTHER AND A CHILD CAN
BE VERY CONFLICTED.
PERHAPS HER SON GOT WORSE AS
TIME WENT ON.
HE WAS OUT OF CONTROL.
IT SOUNDS LIKE FOR SOME REASON
THEY WERE TOO ISOLATED THAT THE
MOTHER AND SON HAD TOO MUCH TIME
TOGETHER.
I DON'T KNOW HOW MUCH OUTSIDE
INTERVENTION SHE ASKED FOR.
SOUNDS LIKE SHE HOME SCHOOLED
HIM.
>> I HAVE A FEW SECONDS BEFORE
WE GO TO BREAK.
THE IDEA OF A MOTHER KNOWING HER
SON HAD PROBLEMS AND THEN TAKING
HIM TO A GUN RANGE, HAVING THESE
HIGH POWERED WEAPONS AND CLIPS
OBVIOUSLY.
A GLOCK AND A BUSHMASTER WHICH
IS LIKE AN AR 15 ASSAULT RIFLE.
WHAT WAS SHE THINKING?
>> YOU DON'T HAVE TO HAVE A
PH.D. TO SAY IT DOESN'T SOUND
LIKE A GOOD IDEA.
EVEN IF SHE SOUGHT HELP FOR HIM,
WE DON'T KNOW IF SHE DID OR NOT.
IT'S HARD TO GET HELP FOR A KID
LIKE THIS, TO DE CATAIN A KID T
GET ADEQUATE TREATMENT IT IS
VERY HARD IN THE YEAR 2012 TO DO
THAT.
>> DOCTOR, BOTH OF YOU STAY WITH
US.
>>> COMING UP THIS WEEK THE
BURIALS WILL START.
HOW CAN A PARENT POSSIBLY HEAL
FROM SUCH A TRAUMATIC EVENT.
LATER THE ROLE OF RELIGION AND
FAITH AND HEALING IN THIS
PROCESS.
I THOUGHT I'D START THE VIDEO
BY SHOWING YOU
THE APARTMENT BUILDING
WHERE THE FIRE WAS.
WHEN THINGS LIKE THIS HAPPEN,
I THINK YOU FIND
A NEW PERSPECTIVE ON LIFE.
RED CROSS PUT US IN A HOTEL
SO WE WERE ABLE
TO STAY TOGETHER.
WE'RE STRONG
AND IF WE OVERCAME THAT
OR IF WE CAN OVERCOME THAT...
WE CAN OVERCOME ANYTHING.
[ SNIFFLES ]
♪
DAVINO.
>> SHE HEARD EVERYTHING THE
SHOTS AND THE DOORS SLAMMING AND
PEOPLE YELLING.
SHE JUST WANTED TO COME HOME.
HER HEART WAS RACING.
SHE WAS SCARED.
>> THE FIRST FUNERAL FOR ONE OF
THE YOUNG ANGELS KILLED IN THE
SHOOTING IS SET FOR TOMORROW.
6-YEAR-OLD NOAH POZNER WILL BE
LAID TO REST IN FAIRFIELD,
CONNECTICUT.
WITH ME IS GRIEF COUNSELOR
ROBINWOODMAN AND DR. SAM NOW IS
STILL WITH US.
TALK TO ME ABOUT THIS WEEK
PARENTS BAUURYING THEIR CHILDRE.
IT'S COUNTER INDUE TIVE THAT'S
SUPPOSED TO BE THE OTHER WAY.
>> WHAT HAPPENS IS THEY FEEL
LIKE IT SHOULD HAVE BEEN THEM.
THERE'S NOTHING WORSE FOR A
PARENT TO GO THROUGH.
AND AT THIS POINT WHEN YOU ARE
SEEING THESE PARENTS ARE IN
SHOCK, THEY ARE NUMB, THEY ARE
OVERWHELMED WITH THEIR FEELINGS.
THEY MAY NOT EVEN FEEL THEIR
FEELINGS.
THEY HAVE BEEN ALMOST
DISASSOCIATED WITH THEIR
FEELINGS.
YOU TALK TO PEOPLE AT THIS STAGE
AND THEY WILL TELL YOU LIKE THEY
ARE GOING THROUGH THE MOTIONS
AND THEY ARE LIKE A ROBOT.
ACTUALLY SOMETIMES IT'S THE
PEOPLE AROUND THEM THAT ARE
LITERALLY KIND OF CARRYING
THROUGH THESE VERY DIFFICULT
STEPS.
>> HOW DO THEY COME OUT OF IT?
WHEN DO YOU GET OUT FROM UNDER
THE CLOUD?
YOU HAVE OTHER CHILDREN AT HOME.
CHILDREN WHO ARE SUFFERING AS
WELL.
>> SOMETIMES THAT'S WHAT BRINGS
YOU AT LEAST INTO LIVING.
IT DOESN'T NECESSARILY BRING YOU
INTO A FULL HAPPY LIFE BECAUSE
THERE'S A WHOLE THAT REALLY
DOESN'T GET FILLED BUT WHAT THEY
DO IS FIND A WAY EVENTUALLY IF
THEY CAN TO HAVE THEIR GRIEF
TRACK IN THEIR LIFE AND THEN THE
LIVING TRACK OF THEIR LIFE.
AND THEY SOMETIME HAVE TO KEEP A
FOOT IN BOTH WORLDS AND
EVENTUALLY THE LIVING PART CAN
GET BIGGER.
>> YOU DO THIS FOR A LIVING.
YOU RECOMMEND THE PARENTS WHO
ARE BURYING THEIR CHILDREN THAT
THEY GET COUNSELING, STAY IN
TOUCH AND NOT BE WITHDRAWN AND
WHAT ELSE?
>> WELL, I THINK WHAT YOU SEE
OVER TIME IS THAT EVERYBODY HAS
A DIFFERENT REACTION.
THERE AREN'T STAGES OF GRIEF.
IT IS THROUGH OUT YOUR LIFE.
IT INVOLVES STAGES.
AT A CERTAIN TIME YOUR FRIENDS
CHILDREN ARE GRADUATING FROM
HIGH SCHOOL AND YOURS AREN'T.
YOU START TO PAY ATTENTION TO
HOW YOU ARE DOING.
THERE ARE A CERTAIN NUMBER WHO
NEED SPECIFIC HELP TO HELP THEM
LEARN HOW TO COPE AND ACTUALLY
CAN BE VERY SUCCESSFUL WITH AND
FIND SOME KIND OF MEANING AND
NEW PEOPLE IN THEIR LIFE.
>> THEY TALK ABOUT POST
TRAUMATIC STRESS SYNDROME IN
WARS.
THESE KIDS HAVE SEEN HELL A LOT
OF THEM.
>> THEY WERE IN A MINI WAR WHEN
YOU THINK ABOUT IT.
THE RAMPAGE.
WHEN I FIRST HEARD THE NEWS I
WAS LIKE IS THIS ANOTHER
TERRORIST ATTACK.
IT ALMOST SOUNDED LIKE THAT.
WHAT POST TRAUMATIC STRESS
DISORDER IS HAVING OO FRIGHTENED
REACTION.
WE USUALLY WALK AROUND THINKING
WE ARE SAFE AND THE WORLD IS
SAFE.
THERE IS A RECOGNITION THE WORLD
IS NO LONGER SAFE OR IN YOUR
CONTROL.
>> WE HEARD LAST NIGHT ABOUT A
CHILD WHO WAS AFRAID TO HAVE HER
FATHER LEAVE HER SIDE FOR GOOD
REASONS.
>> THERE WILL BE REGRESSION,
NIGHTMARES SOMETIMES PANIC
ATTACKS.
FEAR TO GO NEAR THE SCHOOL, TO
BE SEPARATED FROM A PARENT.
MAYBE TO HAVE SLEEP OVERS.
SO PARENTS CAN JUST BE AWARE OF
THIS WORK WITH THEIR
PEDIATRICIAN.
SOUNDS LIKE THE TOWN IS REALLY
HELPING OUT AND BEING A RESOURCE
FOR THE ENTIRE COMMUNITY.
>> THE QUESTION THAT -- THE
BIGGER QUESTION IS HOW DOES THE
TOWN HEEL?
>> IT WAS PUT TOGETHER.
DON'T YOU THINK THEY HAVE EACH
OTHER?
BEING CONNECTED TO EACH OTHER.
ALSO NOT TOMORROW NOT JUST NEXT
WEEK BUT IT IS OVER MANY MONTHS
SO YOU KEEP REACHING OUT SO
THESE PEOPLE DON'T FEEL ALONE.
>> THERE WAS NO QUESTION THAT
EVERYONE IN THAT TOWN WAS
AFFECTED IN ONE WAY OR ANOTHER.
HOW HARD IS IT TO IDENTIFY ONE
WHO MIGHT COMMIT A CRIME LIKE
THIS?
>> I DON'T KNOW ABOUT THAT BUT
THESE INDIVIDUALS ARE LIKE
LITTLE TERRORISTS OR BIG
TERRORISTS.
THEY LIVE IN THEIR FAMILIES AND
THEIR PARENTS AND OTHERS SPOUSES
AND ADULTS THEY ARE AFRAID OF
THEM.
IT IS DIFFICULT TO GET PEOPLE
LIKE THIS TO STAY IN HELL TO
DETAIN THEM.
LET ME TELL YOU THERE IS NO PILL
THAT IS GOING TO CURE THIS
POSITION.
THERE MIGHT BE A PRAYER BUT
PEOPLE WHO ARE EVIL ARE NOT
AMENABLE TO MENTAL HEALTH
PROFESSIONALS.
>>> THE ILLNESS CONVERSATION ON
AMERICA WHICH I THOUGHT WAS
EXCELLENT.
THERE IS TALK YOU CAN'T GET HELP
UNLESS THEY START COMMITTING
CRIMES.
>> THIS IS AFTER THEY COMMITTED
A CRIME.
YOU AREUTELY CORRECT
GETTING THEM HELP BEFORE THAT IS
LIKE CLIMBING MOUNT EVEREST
BAREFOOT.
>> WE NEED TO TALK ABOUT THE
DEEPER ISSUES SO WE DON'T HAVE
THIS HAPPEN A YEAR FROM NOW.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT THE CAUSE FOR
THESE SPREE KILLINGS REALLY IS.
>> ALL OF THE BURIALS AS A
COUNTRY HOW DO WE DEAL WITH
THAT.
MY HEART BREAKS.
I HA
I AM A MOTHER.
I HAVE SEEN CHILD ABUSE AND
HOMICIDE CASES.
THIS ONE JUST BREAKS YOUR HEART.
>> I THINK WHAT YOU DO IS YOU
PAY ATTENTION TO THE PEOPLE THAT
ARE RIGHT IN YOUR WORLD TO HELP
THEM WITH THIS AND ALSO LEARN TO
BE HE KNOWS IS TIVE TO THE OTHER
PEOPLE WHO ALSO NEED EXTRA HELP.
>> GREAT PANEL DR. LESLIE,
DR. GOOD MAN AND DR. STABENOW.
>>> THESE ARE WITHOUT A DOUBT
THE MOST DIFFICULT OF TIMES.
CAN FAITH HEAL ALL WOUNDS?
>> LET THE LITTLE CHILDREN COME
TO ME JESUS SAID.
DO NOT HINDER THEM.
FOR TO SUCH BELONGS THE KINGDOM
OF HEAVEN.
GOD HAS CALLED THEM ALL HOME.
MAY GOD BLESS AND KEEP THOSE WE
HAVE LOST IN HIS HEAVENLY PLACE.
MAY HE GRACE THOSE WE STILL HAVE
WITH HIS HOLY COMFORT.
>> WITH ME IS JACK MONDAY A
MEMBER OF BILLY GRAHAM'S RAP HID
RESPONSE TEAM AND JARROD MURRAY
PAST FORE
PASTOR OF HOLY FAMILY PARISH.
>> I AM GOING TO START WITH YOU.
YOU WERE PART OF BILLY GRAHAM'S
RAPID RESPONSE TEAM.
I UNDERSTAND YOUR TEAM ARRIVED
IN NEWTOWN ON FRIDAY THE VERY
G
DAY THIS HAPPENED.
TELL US WHAT YOU SAW?
>> YES, AFTER ARRIVING WE MADE
CONTACT WITH THE STATE POLICE
AND THE FIRE HERE IN NEWTOWN.
BECAUSE OF OUR CHAPLAIN HAVING A
POLICE BACK GROUND AND FIRE
BACKGROUND THEY WERE WELCOMELED
IMMEDIATELY AT THE VOLUNTEER
FIRE DEPARTMENTS AND ESCORTED TO
THE EMERGENCY OPERATIONS CENTER.
>> AND JACK YOU DO THIS
REGULARLY AS PARTED OF THIS
RESPONSE TEAM YOU GO ALL OVER
THE COUNTRY.
>> ACTUALLY, WE HAVE BEEN DOING
THIS SINCE SEPTEMBER 11TH WE
HAVE RESPONDED TO 154 DISASTERS
TEN OF WHICH HAVE BEEN ON MASS
SHOOTINGS.
>> I AM GOING TOING TO YOU
FATHER MURRAY.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR BEING WITH
US TODAY.
I GUESS THE QUESTION WE ALL ASK
IS AN ALL KNOWING POWERFUL
LOVING GOD ALLOW THIS TO HAPPEN.
>> THE WAY I LOOK AT THE
QUESTION IS, IF YOU WANT TO KNOW
WHAT THE WORLD IS LIKE WITHOUT
GOD THIS IS AN EXAMPLE.
THIS MAN TURNED AWAY FROM GOD
OBVIOUSLY AND DID SOMETHING
TREMENDOUS.
KILLING YOUR OWN MOTHER AND
KILLING INNOCENT CHILDREN SO
AGAINST NATURE COMPLETELY
AGAINST THE TEN COMMANDMENTS.
GOD IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR THIS.
WE ARE AS HUMAN BEINGS ARE FREE
CHOICES.
I NOTICE THAT PUBLIC REACTION IS
NOT TO TURN AWAY FROM GOD AND
BLAME HIM.
IT'S TO GO TO GOD AND PRAY FOR
SYMPATHY AND THE VICTIMS AND
CONSTELLATION.
>> YOU KNOW FATHER CAN YOU
UNDERSTAND A PARENT WHO LOST AN
ANGEL AND WILL BE BURYING THESE
CHILDREN THIS WEEK CAN TURN AWAY
AND SAY, HOW COULD GOD TAKE MY
CHILD FROM ME?
>>> OO GOD DIDN'T DO IT.
THE MESSAGE WE SAY IS GOD LOVES
THAT CHILD.
THAT'S THE HOPE OF CHRISTIANITY.
JESUS HAVING HIS LITTLE ONES.
THE ANSWER IS MORE COMPLICATED
THAN SOMEBODY MIGHT LIKE.
WE NEVER KNOW WHEN THE CALL IS
GOING TO COME.
THIS IS HORRIBLE IT SHOULDN'T
HAPPEN.
ON THE OTHER HAND IT'S A PROOF
WE HAVE TO FIGHT EVIL NOT
TOLERATE IT.
>> I WENT TO CATHOLIC SCHOOLS
AND I AM A CATHOLIC.
I STAUND WE HAVE BEEN GIVEN FREE
WILL, BUT YOU KNOW THE ABILITY
TO CHOOSE WHAT WE WANT TO DO IS
STILL -- IT ALLOWS THOSE OTHER
PEOPLE TO CHOOSE EVIL.
IT IS SOMETHING WE CAN'T STOP.
>> WE CAN OFFER ANOTHER LAW, A
LAW OF LOVE AND TRAINING IN
SYMPATHY.
IT WILL BE INTERESTING TO READ
WHAT PART RELIGION PLAYED IN HIS
PLAN'S LIFE, IF ANYTHING.
>> WE NEED TO BE MORE RAE LIG
GUS AS A NATION.
>> JACK MONDAY, WE HEAR FROM THE
FATHER ROBY PARKER OF ONE OF THE
CHILDREN.
HE SAID, I AM NOT ANGRY.
I FOR GIVE.
DOES THAT SURPRISE YOU?
HAVE YOU HEARD THAT BEFORE?
>> I HAVE.
AS WE RESPOND TO DISASTERS.
WE MEET WITH PEOPLE WHO HAVE A
FOUNDATION OF FAITH.
A FAITH IN CHRIST.
WE HAVE PEOPLE WHO DON'T HAVE A
FOUNDATION OF FAITH AT ALL.
IT IS A TESTIMONY OF WHAT GODS
HAS DONE IN SOMEONE'S LIFE THAT
IS FOUNDATIONAL.
THEY HAVE A FAITH IN CHRIST.
THEY KNOW THAT IS THEIR SOURCE
OF HOPE, THEIR SOURCE OF COMFORT
AND WHEN THEY DO TURN TO CHRIST
AND TO GOD'S WORD THAT OFFERS
THAT HOPE THEY ARE THE ONES.
NOT TO SAY THEY DON'T HURT, THEY
DON'T SUFFER, IT'S STILL AN
AGONIZING LOSS FOR THEM.
NO DIFFERENT THAN ANY ONE ELSE.
IT LOOKS LIKE A REALITY WHEN YOU
HAVE A FAITH IN CHRIST AND YOU
CAN PUT YOUR COMPETENCE IN HIM
AND FOCUS HIS FOLKS ON HIS TEAM.
OO WILL OO IT IS NOT END OF THE
STORY.
THERE IS HOPE.
>> FATHER MURRAY FOR THOSE
PEOPLE WHO HAVEN'T HAD GOD IN
THEIR LIVES, WHO HAVEN'T BEEN
PRACTICING RELIGION PEOPLE SAY I
DON'T BELIEVE IN GOD.
DO YOU THINK THERE'S A CHANCE
THEY WILL COME TO GOD AS A
RESULT OF THIS?
>> THE ERUPTION OF HELL INTO AN
OTHERWISE PEACEFUL COMMUNITY
THERE IS MORE TO LIFE THAN WHAT
WE SIMPLY CHOOSE TO DO.
THE TO TURN TO GOD AND KNOW
WHAT'S RIGHT.
>> I WANT TO THANK YOU FOR BEING
WITH US AND THANK YOU FOR ALL
THAT YOU DO.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US THIS
EVENING.
>> THAT'S IT FOR OUR SPECIAL
EDITION OF "JUSTICE."
AS WE SIGN OFF TONIGHT OUR
THOUGHTS AND PRAYERS GO TO ALL
OF THOSE AFFECTED BY THE HORROR
THAT HAS VISITED US THIS FAPAST
FRIDAY.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WULGS.