YOU'LL GET THIS MAGNIFIER
WITH L.E.D. LIGHT
ABSOLUTELY FREE.
WHEN YOU CALL THE EXPERTS
AT One Reverse Mortgage TODAY,
YOU'LL LEARN THE BENEFITS
OF A GOVERNMENT-INSURED
REVERSE MORTGAGE.
IT WILL ELIMINATE
YOUR MONTHLY MORTGAGE PAYMENTS
AND GIVE YOU TAX-FREE CASH
FROM THE EQUITY IN YOUR HOME.
AND HERE'S THE BEST PART --
YOU STILL OWN YOUR HOME.
TAKE CONTROL
OF YOUR RETIREMENT TODAY.
♪
>> FIRST FROM FOX AT 3:00, A
HORRIFIC MURDER INSIDE AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
FOX NEWS HAS CONFIRMED UP TO 27
PEOPLE ARE DEAD INCLUDING WHAT
WE HEAR NOW AN UPDATED NUMBER
FOR THE CHILDREN, 20 CHILDREN.
THAT WOULD MAKE THIS THE MOST
DEADLY SCHOOL SHOOTING IN UNITED
STATES HISTORY SECOND ONLY TO
THE MASSACRE AT VIRGINIA TECH IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, 50 MILES
SOUTHWEST OF CONNECTICUT STATE
CAPITAL, AND 60 MILES FROM OUR
STUDIO IN NEW YORK CITY.
COPS IDENTIFIED THE SHOOTER AS
24-YEAR-OLD MAN, RYAN LANZA.
POLICE SAY AT 9:30 THEY RECEIVED
AN EMERGENCY CALL FROM THE
SCHOOL RIGHT AFTER THE SCHOOL,
OR AROUND THE TOWN THE SCHOOL
USUALLY LOOKS THE DOORS.
THE KILLER, DRESSED IN MOCK
MILITARY GEAR, ARMED WITH TWO
GUNS AS HE OPENED FIRE INSIDE
THE SCHOOL.
HIS VICTIMS?
TEACHERS AND CHILDREN.
>> WE SPOTTED THE TROOPERS AND
THE NEWTOWN POLICE ENTERED THE
SCHOOL AND ME BEGAN A COMPLETE
ACTIVE SHOOTER SEVEN INCLUDING
CHECKING EVERY DOOR AND EVERY
CRACK AND EVERY PORTION OF THE
SCHOOL.
OUR OBJECTIVE WAS TO EVACUATE AS
QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE.
>> OFFICIALS HAVE NOT CONFIRMED
THE NUMBER OF DEAD SAYING THAT
THEY ARE IN THE PROCESS OF
NOTIFYING FAMILIES.
THE OFFICIALS SAID THE SHOOTER
DIED INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
IT IS UNCLEAR IF HE TOOK HIS OWN
LIFE OR IF POLICE KILLED HIM.
THERE ARE REPORTS THAT THE MAN'S
MOTHER WAS FOUND DEAD AND
INVESTIGATORS ARE QUESTIONING A
SECOND PERSON.
THIS IS A DEVELOPING STORY.
JONATHAN HUNT IS LIVE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT THE SCENE.
>>Jonathan: HARD TO IMAGINE
AND HARD TO PUT IN WORDS THE
TERROR INFLICTED UPON SANDY HOOK
WHERE WE ARE, PART OF THE
GREATER NEWTOWN AREA.
OR UPON THE CHILDREN OF SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY.
IT IS PERHAPS DESCRIBED BEST BY
ONE OF THE CHILDREN THEMSELVES
WHO WAS LED AWAY FROM THE SCHOOL
EARLY TODAY.
LISTEN.
>> WE WERE JUST IN THE MIDDLE OF
GYM AND WE HEARD GUNSHOTS.
THE POWER WENT OUT.
THE GYM TEACHERS DIRECTED US TO
STAY AGAINST THE WALL AND
EVERYONE STARTED PANICKING.
THEN THE POLICE CAME IN.
THEY ASKED IF HE WAS IN HERE.
WE HAD TO CLIMB INTO THE CLOSETS
AND WE HEARD A LOT MORE GUNSHOTS
AND THE AMBULANCE CAME.
>> THE ONE THING ABOUT THE
CHILDREN IS THAT SOME OF THEM
DON'T UNDERSTAND EXACTLY WHAT
HAPPENED HERE BUT PARENTS
OBVIOUSLY UNDERSTOOD IT ALL TOO
WELL.
YOU CAN ONLY IMAGINE THE TERROR
THAT THEY EXPERIENCED AS THEY
HEARD ABOUT THE SHOOTINGS AND
STARTED RUNNING TOWARD THE
SCHOOL.
HERE IS ONE OF THE PARENTS.
>> MAYHEM IN THE ROOM WITH ALL
THE KIDS AND THE TEACHERS TRYING
TO FIND YOUR KID, IDENTIFY THEM,
TRYING TO FIND OUT THE
SITUATION.
>> THERE ARE NO WORDS.
TERROR AND A SENSE OF IMMEDIATE
URGENCY TO GET TO YOUR CHILD AND
TO BE THERE TO PROTECT THEM.
>> AS HARD AS THE TEACHERS TRIED
TO PROTECT THE CHILDREN, IN
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
TODAY, THE AWFUL NEWS IS THAT 20
CHILDREN WERE AMONG THE TOTAL OF
26 DEAD.
WE DO NOT HAVE FINAL FIGURES.
ALL OF THIS OBVIOUSLY IS VERY
FLUID.
IT COULD CHANGE.
>> WE ASK FOR YOUR PATIENCE AS
WE WORK TO CONFIRM EVERY DETAIL
WE HAVE SO FAR.
THE WIRES, JONATHAN, SHOW THAT
RYAN LANZA'S FATHER WAS KILLED
IN HIS HOME IN NEW JERSEY.
IN ADDITION TO THE NEWS FROM THE
TOP OF THE HOUR, HIS PER, WE
KNOW, THE PER OF THE SHOOTER WAS
FOUND DEAD IN CONNECTICUT.
WE ARE PUTTING TOGETHER A LITTLE
BIT OF WHAT HAPPENED PERHAPS
EARLY THIS MORNING BUT THE
TIMELINE AS WE KNOW WE ARE STILL
DISCOVERING.
WHAT ELSE DO WE KNOW OF THE
SHOOTER?
>>Jonathan: WE ARE TOLD HE WAS
24.
RYAN LANZA WAS HIS NAME.
THERE WAS SOME INITIAL CONFUSION
WITH THE SHOOTER BEING
IDENTIFIED AS A 20-YEAR-OLD.
WE DO KNOW ACCORDING TO
OFFICIALS THAT RYAN LANZA HAS A
20-YEAR-OLD BROTHER.
THAT MAY HAVE BEEN WHERE SOME OF
THE CONFUSION CAME FROM.
ALSO, INTERESTING TO NOTE AS WE
NOTE THAT, THERE WERE REPORTS
THAT POLICE WERE QUESTIONING A
SECOND PERSON IN DETECTION WITH
THE SHOOTINGS THAT THEY
ALLEGEDLY FOUND IN THE WOODS
BEHIND THE SCHOOL.
ALL OF THIS, OBVIOUSLY, IN ITS
EARLY STAGES.
POLICE ARE CONFIRMING JUST NOW
THE SHOOTER DIED INSIDE THE
SCHOOL.
THEY HAVE ALSO CONFIRMED THAT
BOTH THE MOTHER AND FATHER OF
RYAN LANZA HAVE BEEN FOUND DEAD
IN THEIR HOMES.
THE FATHER IN NEW JERSEY, THE
MOTHER HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
SHE WORKED AT THE SCHOOL BUT
POLICE OBVIOUSLY ARE STILL
WORKING THROUGH AT THE WHO OF
LEADS.
>> THE SHOOTER IS DECEASED
INSIDE THE BUILDING.
THERE IS A GREAT DEAL OF WORK
THAT WILL BE UNDERTAKEN
IMMEDIATELY UPON LOCATING THE
SHOOTER.
THERE IS A GREAT DEAL OF SEARCH
WARRANT ACTIVITY AND LAW
ENFORCEMENT ACTIVITY, INSTATE
AND OUT OF STATE TO COVER ALL
THE BASES RELATIVE TO THAT
INDIVIDUAL.
THE SCENE IS SECURE.
>>Jonathan: THE SCENE IS
SECURE.
THE SCHOOL OBVIOUSLY IS A MAJOR
CRIME SCENE RIGHT NOW.
UNIMAGINABLE TO THINK OF THE
SCENE INSIDE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
>> PART OF THE SCREEN THE
VIEWERS CAN SEE WHAT IS
CONTINUING TO BE A LIVE SHOT.
WE SEE A LOT OF RESPONDERS AND
POLICE CARS ON THE SCENE.
TELL US WHERE YOU ARE STANDING
IN RELATION TO THE SCHOOL.
ALSO, TALK TO US ABOUT WHAT YOU
HAVE SEEN FROM THE RESPONDERS
THAT HAS STAYED ON THAT SCENE
FOR THE LAST SEVERAL HOURS.
>>Jonathan: WE ARE AT A MEDIA
STAGING AREA THE POLICE HAVE
ESSENTIALLY SET UP.
THE SCHOOL IS A LITTLE BIT
BEHIND ME ACROSS THE FIELDS.
IT IS ON COMPLETE LOCKDOWN.
EVERY STREET IN THIS VERY SMALL
TOWN OF SANDY HOOK IS SHUT OFF
BY THE COPS FOR OBVIOUS REASONS.
THE PEOPLE OF THE TOWN AS WE
WILL HEAR LATER, THEY ARE NOT
REALLY WANTING TO TALK TO THE
MEDIA.
VERY, VERY UNDERSTANDABLE.
EVERYONE HERE IS IN A COMPLETE
STATE OF SHOCK.
WE DID HEAR SOME REPORTS THAT
SOME OF THE FIREFIGHTERS --
THERE IS A FIREHOUSE CLOSE TO
THE SCHOOL -- SOME OF THE
FIREFIGHTERS WALKED OUT IN TEARS
AND IF IT IS REDUCING GROWN MEN
TO TEARS YOU CAN ONLY IMAGINE
WHAT THE SMALL CHILDREN WENT
THROUGH.
MANY WERE LED OUT THROUGH THE
SCHOOL IN THE IMMEDIATE
AFTERMATH OF THE SHOTTING BY
THEIR TEACHERS AND BY POLICE.
THEY WERE TOLD TO COVER THEIR
EYES.
ONE CAN ONLY ASSUME THEY WERE
TOLD TO DO THAT BECAUSE THEY
WERE WALKING AROUND BODIES OF
KIDS WHO USED TO BE THEIR
CLASSMATES.
>> BACK TO JONATHAN WHEN WE GET
MORE NEWS.
WE ARE AWAITING A NEWS
CONFERENCE FROM THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT AND A STATEMENT FROM
PRESIDENT OBAMA IN SEVEN
MINUTES.
NOW A WOMAN AND HER
EIGHT-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER, A
STUDENT, BOTH JOIN US ON THE
PHONE.
BRENDA, AS A MOTHER, CAN YOU
TELL US ABOUT WHAT YOU HAVE
LEARNED.
>>CALLER: WELL, WHEN I FIRST
CAME HOME I ASSUMED IT WAS ONLY
THE PRINCIPAL THAT WAS KILLED.
THEN I FOUND OUT THAT 26 PEOPLE.
I TALKED TO SOME FRIENDS AND
THERE ARE CHILDREN THAT ARE
UNACCOUNTED FOR AND THEY WILL
NOT TELL THE PARENTS WHERE THEY
ARE.
THAT IS ALL WE KNOW SINCE I LEFT
THE SCHOOL.
>> SO THERE IS A LOT OF
CONFUSION.
THAT HAS BEEN OUR EXPERIENCE
WITH THE STORY.
YOUR DAUGHTER IS ON THE LINE,
WHAT GRADE ARE YOU IN?
>>CALLER: THIRD GRADE.
>> WHAT HAPPENED AT SCHOOL?
>>CALLER: WE WERE ABOUT TO HAVE
SOCIAL STUDIES AND MATH WE AND
HEARD BIG BANGS, LIKE GOT SHOTS
AND MISS MARTIN WENT TO LOCK THE
DOOR AND SHE TOLD US TO GO IN
THE CORNER AND MISS MARTIN
CALLED 9-1-1 AND THEY CAME.
>> THE HIS CAME?
>>CALLER: YES.
>> THAT IS IT RIGHT NEW.
CAN YOU TELL ME ABOUT HOW YOU
FELT WHEN THAT WAS HAPPENING?
>>CALLER: I FELT SCARED.
AND EVERYONE WAS SHAKING.
>> I AM SURE.
IT SOUNDS LIKE YOUR TEACHER DID
A GOOD JOB, THOUGH.
MISS MARTIN IS HER NAME?
>>CALLER: YES.
>> HOW DID YOU GET OUT OF THE
SCHOOL?
>>CALLER: THE COPS KNOCKED ON
THE DOOR AND HE TOLD US TO COME
OUT AND WE RAN OUT.
>> YOU WERE PRETTY HAPPY TO SEE
YOUR MOM?
>>CALLER: YES.
>> TELL US HOW YOU FIRST LEARNED
ABOUT THE SHOOTING AND HOW WERE
YOU ABLE TO REUNITE WITH YOUR
DAUGHTER.
>>CALLER: I GOT AN EMERGENCY
PHONE CALL THERE WAS A SHOOTING
AND THE SCHOOL WAS ON LOCK DOWN
AND THEN I GOT A TEXT FROM AP
THAT THERE WAS A SHOOTING AT A
SCHOOL IN SANDY HOOK AND I
THOUGHT, THAT THAT IS OUR
SCHOOL.
I WENT TO SCHOOL AND THERE WERE
HYSTERICAL MOMS AND SHE SAID
WHAT IS GOING ON, AND SHE SAID
THE PRINCIPAL WAS DEAD AND THE
CHILDREN CAME OUT WITH BLOOD.
I WAS NUMB.
IT WAS THE WORST MOMENT OF MY
LIFE AND I SAW HER COME FROM THE
SCHOOL, FROM THE FIREHOUSE, WITH
HER CLASS, COME FROM NEXT TO THE
SCORE AND I BROKE INTO TEARS,
THE HAPPIEST MOMENT OF MY LIFE.
>> WHAT RELIEF.
WE CAN ONLY MA'AM HOW THAT FELT.
WE ARE SO HAPPY YOU WERE ABLE TO
SEE YOUR DAUGHTER AT THAT
MOMENT.
CAN YOU TELL ME, WHEN YOU ARE IN
SCHOOL, WE HAVE HEARD FROM
PEOPLE IN THE TOWN THAT
SOMETIMES YOU PRACTICE EMERGENCY
DRILLS.
HAVE YOU PRACTICED EMERGENCY
DRILLS LIKE THE ONE YOU DID
TODAY?
>>CALLER: NOT REALLY.
GOING OUT AND WAITING UNTIL THE
PEOPLE CALL US.
>> DID YOU SEE ANYTHING WHEN YOU
WALKED OUT THE SCHOOL?
>>CALLER: NO.
>> WHAT IS NEXT, MOM IN HOW DO
YOU TALK TO YOUR DAUGHTER ABOUT
THIS?
WHAT ARE THEY TELLING YOU, THE
SCHOOL OFFICIALS, ABOUT WHAT IS
NEXT FOR PARENTS?
>>Guest: OBVIOUSLY EVERYTHING
IS CANCELED FOR TODAY.
WE ARE JUST, I WANT TO KNOW HOW
PERSONAL FRIENDS ARE AND MAKE
SURE THE KIDS ARE SAFE, MY
FRIENDS' CHILDREN I WANT TO MAKE
SURE THEY ARE SAFE.
WE ARE JUST DAILYING WITH IT.
>> CAN YOU TELL ME ONE LAST
THING, HOW DID IT FEEL WHEN YOU
SAW YOUR MOM AT THE FIRE HOUSE?
>>CALLER: I WAS REALLY HAPPY.
>> I BET.
WE ARE HAPPY.
THAT IS AN EMOTION YOU BOTH
SHARED.
THANK YOU, BOTH, FRIEND DA AND
SOPHIA.
WE ARE SO GLAD YOUR DAUGHTER IS
SAFE.
>> THANK YOU TO BOTH OF YOU.
REMEMBER, SHE IS JUST EIGHT, ONE
OF THE CHILDREN INSIDE THE
SCHOOL, NEARLY 700 STUDENTS IN
THE SCHOOL, KINDERGARTEN THROUGH
4th, YOU THINK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IS OLD ARE KIDS BUT AT
THIS SCHOOL IT ONLY GOES UP TO
THE 4th GRADE.
WE WILL WAIT FOR THE PRESIDENT.
HE WILL MAKE A STATEMENT AND WE
WILL WAIT TO HEAR FROM HIM.
SPEAKER BOEHNER SAYS HE IS
LOWERING THE FLAGS OVER CAPITOL
HILL OVER THIS INCIDENT.
BUT, FIRST WE RETURN TO THE
SCENE, OUR REPORTER ISIN'ING US.
>>Reporter: THE LATEST
INFORMATION WE HAVE BEEN HEARING
IS THAT THE GUNMAN WHO KILLED AT
LEAST 27 PERSONS, 18 OF THEM
ELEMENTARY SCHOOLCHILDREN,
MEANING SOMEWHERE BETWEEN TEN
AND UNDER, HE WAS FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, A SMALL SUBURBAN
COMMUNITY, QUIET SUBURBAN
COMMUNITY, WITH NO CRIME.
HE, SOURCES ARE SAYING, HE WENT
TO EMERGENCY AND KILL A RELATIVE
THERE.
THEN HE CAME HERE THIS MORNING
TO NEWTOWN AND WALKED INTO THE
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL WHERE HIS
MOTHER TEACHES, SHOT AND KILLED
HER MOTHER AND SHOT AND KILLED
MOST OF THE CHILDREN IN THE
CLASSROOM, THE 18 CHILDREN WERE
IN THE CLASSROOM.
THE POLICE HAVE RECOVERED TWO
HANDGUNS AND POSSIBLY A .223
HIGH CALIBER RIFLE HE MAY HAVE
USED.
HE WAS WEARING, DRESSED IN BLACK
WITH BODY ARMOR, AND CARRYING
THE TWO PISTOLS.
AFTER HE SHOT HIS MOTHER AND
KILLED THE CHILDREN IN THAT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL CLASSROOM, HE
WALKED DOWN THE HALLWAY AND AT
THAT POINT, THIS IS A ONE-LEVEL
SCHOOL BUILDING, THE PRINCIPAL
CAME OUT OF THE PRINCIPAL'S
OFFICE WITH TWO TEACHERS AND AT
THAT POINT THE ALLEGED GUNMAN
SHOT AND KILLED THE PRINCIPAL.
A TOTAL OF 27 PERSONS KILLED, 18
OF THEM CHILDREN, AND NINE
ADULTS AND WE HEAR THAT SOME
CHILDREN MAY ALSO BE IN SERIOUS
CONDITION AND MAY HAVE ALSO DIED
SO THE NUMBERS MAY GO UP TO 30
BUT THAT IS NOT OFFICIALLY
CONFIRMED.
THAT IS THE SITUATION LIKE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> HE WAS STANDING DOWN THE
STREET FROM THE SCENE AND WE ARE
SKIPPING OVER A FEW STATES HERE
AS WE CONTINUE TO WATCH THE
STORY.
THE CRIME.
THE MURDERS HAPPENED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, BUT THE SHOOTER MAY
HAVE LIVED IN NEW JERSEY, WHERE
HIS FATHER WAS FOUND KILLED.
HIS MOTHER ALSO FUND KILLED IN
NEW STUN CONNECTICUT.
WE ARE JUST NOW PUTTING TOGETHER
THE STORY AS IT COMES TO OUR
NEWSROOM.
RIGHT NOW, 20 CHILDREN HAVE
DIED.
THAT IS THE LATEST.
THAT NUMBER HAS CHANGED THE LAST
SEVERAL HOURS.
WE WILL CONTINUE TO KEEP YOU
UPDATED.
THE PRESIDENT IS SET TO MAKE
REMARKS ABOUT THE SHOOTING
TODAY.
>> I HAVE SPOKEN WITH THE
GOVERNOR THIS AFTERNOON AND FBI
DIRECTOR MUELLER.
I OFFERED THE GOVERNOR MY
CONDOLENCES ON BEHALF OF THE
NATION AND MADE IT CLEAR HE
WILL HAVE EVERY SINGLE RESOURCE
THAT HE NEEDS TO INVESTIGATE
THIS HEINOUS CRIME, CARE FOR THE
VICTIMS, COUNSEL THEIR FAMILIES.
WE HAVE ENDURED TOO MANY OF THE
TRAGEDIES IN THE PAST FEW YEARS.
EACH TIME I LEARN THE NEWS I
REACT NOT AS A PRESIDENT BUT AS
ANYONE ELSE WOULD, AS A PARENT.
THAT WAS ESPECIALLY TRUE TODAY.
I KNOW THERE IS NOT A PARENT IN
AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF FIVE AND TEN.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIKES
AHEAD OF THEM: BIRTHDAYS,
GRADUATIONS, WEDDINGS, KIDS OF
THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE TEACHERS
MEN AND WOMEN WHO DEVELOPED
THEIR LIVES TO HELP OUR CHILDREN
FULFILL THEIR DREAMS.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN TODAY FOR
THE PARENTS AND GRANDPARENTS AND
SISTERS AND BROTHERS OF THE
LITTLE CHILDREN AND FOR THE
FAMILIES OF THE ADULTS WHO WERE
LOST.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN FOR THE
PARENTS OF THE SURVIVORS, AS
WELL, FOR AS BLESSED AS THEY ARE
TO HAVE THEIR CHILDREN HOME
TONIGHT THEY KNOW THAT THEIR
CHILDREN'S INNOCENCE HAS BEEN
TORN AWAY FROM THEM TOO EARLY
AND THERE ARE IN WORDS THAT WILL
EASE THEIR PAIN.
AS A COUNTRY WE HAVE BEEN
THROUGH THIS TOO MANY TIMES.
WHETHER IT IS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IN NEWTOWN OR A MOVIE THEATER IN
AURORA OR A STREET CORNER IN
CHICAGO, THE MAINS ARE OUR
NEIGHBORHOODS AND THE CHILDREN
ARE OUR CHILDREN.
WE ARE GOING TO HAVE TO COME
FOLK AND TAKE MEANINGFUL ACTION
TO PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE
THIS REGARDLESS OF THE POLITICS.
THIS EVENING, MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT EVERY PARENT WILL
DO, HUG OUR CHILDREN TIGHTER AND
WE WILL TEMPERATURE THEM WE LOVE
THEM AND REMIND EACH OTHER HOW
DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT.
THEY NEED ALL OF US, RIGHT NOW,
IN DAYS TO COME, THE COMMUNITY
NEEDS US TO BE AT OUR BEST AS
AMERICANS, AND I WILL DO
EVERYTHING IN MY POWER AS
PRESIDENT TO HELP BECAUSE WHILE
NOTHING CAN FILL THE SPACE OF A
LOST CHILD OR LOVED ONE ALL OF
US CAN EXTEND A HAND TO THOSE IN
NEED TO REMIND THEM THAT WE ARE
THERE FOR THEM, THAT WE ARE
PRAYING FOR THEM, THAT THE LOVE
THEY FELT FOR THOSE THEY LOST
ENDURES NOT JUST IN THEIR
MEMORIES BUT ALSO IN OURS.
MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF THE
VICTIMS AND IN THE WORDS OF
SCRIPTURE "HEAL THE BROKEN
HEARTED AND BIND UP THEIR WOUND
WOUNDS."
>> AN EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT OBAMA
MAKING A STATEMENT ABOUT THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING THAT TRANSPIRED
THIS MORNING ON A QUIET WINTER
MORNING, FRIDAY INWE ARE MORNING
RIGHT BEFORE THE HOLIDAYS IN
CONNECTICUT.
THE PRESIDENT REFLECTING HOW SO
MANY OF US FEEL.
OUR HEARTS ARE BREAKING WITH OUR
FELLOW AMERICANS IN CONNECTICUT.
WE WILL LOOK AT A COUPLE OF
THINGS HAPPENING AROUND THE
COUNTRY WILL WE ARE ALL TAKING
THIS IN.
WHAT YOU ARE SEEING IS THE FLAG
AT HALF STAFF AT THE WHITE
HOUSE.
THE PRESIDENT HAS ORDERED THAT
TO HAPPEN AS A WAY TO HONOR THE
VICTIMS IN CONNECTICUT.
IT WILL BE FLOWN AT HALF STAFF
AND THE WHITE HOUSE SAYS UPON
ALL PUBLIC BUILDINGS AND
GROUNDS, ALL MILITARY POSTS AND
NAVAL STATIONS SO IF YOU SEE
THIS, THIS IS WHAT THIS IS FOR.
WE WILL MOVE TO THE CAPITOL,
SPEAKER BOEHNER EARLY TODAY ALSO
SAYING THAT THE FLAG WILL FLY AT
HALF STAFF AGAIN TO HONOR THE
VICTIMS.
ED HENRY AT THE WHITE HOUSE WITH
US FROM THE BRIEFING ROOM,
STANDING BY.
YOU HAVE SEEN THE REACTION FROM
THE PRESIDENT AND JAKE CARNEY.
VERY REPORT EVERYONE IN THIS
ROOM IS TRYING TO TAKE A BREATH.
I HAVE NEVER SEEN THE PRESIDENT
IN FOUR YEARS GETTING THAT
EMOTIONAL AND WIPING AWAY TEARS
IN FRONT OF US, AND HE STOPPED
HIMSELF SEVERAL TIMES IN THE
REMARKS SAYING OBVIOUSLY THAT HE
IS REACTING NOT JUST AS A
PRESIDENT BUT AS A PARENT AS
MANY OF US OBVIOUSLY ARE ALL
AROUND THE COUNTRY AND THE
WORLD.
IT IS ALSO IMPORTANT TO NOTE
THAT THE BUSINESS OF GOVERNMENT
DOES GO FORWARD.
HE MADE VERY CLEAR HE SPOKE TO
THE GOVERNOR IN CONNECTICUT AND
HE SPOKE TO THE F.B.I. DIRECTOR,
ROBERT MUELLER, AND PLEDGED
EVERY RESOURCE OF THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT WILL BE THERE FOR THE
FOLKS IN CONNECTICUT, STATE AND
LOCAL LAW ENFORCEMENT, TO TELL
WITH THIS TRAGEDY AND HE
OBVIOUSLY GOT INTO THE EMOTIONAL
TOLL OF THIS TRAGEDY THAT GOES
FAR BEYOND WHAT ANY DOLLAR OR
ANY RESOURCE FROM THE GOVERNMENT
CAN DEAL WITH BUT IT IS ALSO
WORTH NOTING AND I WANT TO MAKE
SURE I QUOTE HIP, HE SAID THAT
AT SOME POINT WE WILL "COME
TOGETHER TO TAKE MEANINGFUL
ACTION REGARDLESS OF POLITICS."
INTERESTING BECAUSE EARLY TODAY
AS YOU NOTED JAKE CARNEY WAS
CAREFUL TO SAY IT IS TOO
SOON-TO-BE TALKING ABOUT WHETHER
THERE WILL BE GUN CONTROL
LEGISLATION IN THE DAYS AND
MONTHS AHEAD TO DEAL WITH
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS, PREVENT
FUTURE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS.
AGAIN, THE PRESIDENT DIDN'T USE
THE WORDS GUN CONTROL BUT HE
SAID MEANINGFUL ACTION
REGARDLESS OF POLITICS IN THE
DAYS AHEAD.
HE HAS FACED SOME CRITICISM
AFTER WHAT HE NOTED HAVE BEEN A
SERIES OF TRAGEDIES DURING THE
FIRST TERM OF HIS
ADMINISTRATION.
HE MENTIONED THE MOVIE THEATER
IN AURORA, C TEMPLE
IN WISCONSIN, TUCSON, ARIZONA,
AS WELL, WITH CONGRESSWOMAN
GABRIELLE GIFFORDS SHOT AND
OTHERS LOST THEIR LIBS.
SHE THANKFULLY SURVIVED.
YOU COULD TELL THE EMOTIONAL
TRILLION ON THIS PRESIDENT FROM
ALL THE TRAGEDIES BUT THIS IN
PARTICULAR WITH ALL THE
CHILDREN.
>> WELL PUT.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
BACK TO THE WHITE HOUSE AS WE
GET MORE NEWS.
A FEW DIFFERENT POINTS OF WHAT
THE PRESIDENT HAD TO SAY, AND I
NOTE THAT THE PRESIDENT GAVE US
MORE INFORMATION THAN WE
PREVIOUSLY HAD.
THE PRESIDENT NOTED THAT AS A
VICTIM, IT INCLUDED CHILDREN 5
TO 10 YEARS OLD.
IF YOU ARE JUST GYPPING, WE HAVE
BEEN REPORTING OVER THE LAST
SEVERAL HOURS WE HAVE HEARD OF
THE SHOOTING TAKING PLACE IN A
FEW DIFFERENT LOCATIONS
INCLUDING THE PRINCIPAL'S
OFFICE, THE ELEMENTARY
CLASSROOM, AND THE FIRST GRADE
FROM A PARENT.
THE PRESIDENT NARROWED THAT
DOWN, 5 TO 10 YEARS OLD.
THE QUESTION IS, WHAT HAPPENED
INSIDE THE SCHOOL?
WE DON'T KNOW.
WE DO KNOW THAT THIS IS THE
MURDER OF SOME OF OUR MOST
INNOCENT.
THAT IS THE BIG HEADLINE OF THE
DAY AS WE CONTINUE TO LOOK
THROUGH THE OTHER DETAILS.
NOW IS CHILD PSYCHOLOGIST AND
ASSOCIATE PROFESSOR AND A FORMER
NYPD INVESTIGATOR.
DOCTOR, FIRST THE MURDERER.
DEAD.
THAT ENRAGES US.
THERE IS ANGER AND SADNESS.
WHAT DO YOU DO WITH THE REMAIN
MOTIONS?
>>Guest: WE HAVE HEARD A LOT
OF PEOPLE TALKING ABOUT ARE WE
BECOMING SENSITIZED TO MASS
SHOOTINGS?
WE HEAR ABOUT IT.
WE ARE UPSET FOR A DAY OR TWO
BUT THIS TAKES IT TO ANOTHER
LEVEL.
OUR MOST INNOCENT PEOPLE.
OUR YOUNGEST.
OUR MOST VULNERABLE MEMBERS OF
SOCIETY.
WE SEE THEY ARE NOT SAFE.
THEY HAVE BEEN SLUTTERED --
SLAUGHTERED.
WILL WAKE US UP TO THE ISSUES OF
SOCIETY WHETHER IT IS MEDICAL
LAWS, LEGAL HAWS, GUN LAWS.
I THINK IT IS MUCH TOO EARLY TO
GO INTO THOSE RIGHT NOW.
RIGHT NOW WE HAVE TO FOCUS ON
WHAT IS HAPPENING WITH THE
PARENTS, WITH THE CHILDREN, IN
THAT SCHOOL AND THAT COUNTRY,
WHAT IS HAPPENING WITH US HERE
IN THE UNITED STATES.
THIS IS A GLOBAL ISSUE.
WE HAVE TO ALLOW PEOPLE TO TALK
ABOUT THEIR GRIEF AND RAGE.
>> ONE QUESTION THAT COMES UP,
WHY DOES THIS HAPPEN, AND WHAT
KIND OF PERSON DOES THIS?
>>Guest: IT IS A SICK AND
DERANGED INDIVIDUAL.
SOMETHING WAS GOING ON IN HIS
MIND THAT NOT ONLY TOOK THE
LIKES OF THOSE INNOCENT PEOPLE,
THE SCHOOLTEACHERS AS WELL AS
HIS OWN PARENTS IN TWO SEPARATE
STATES.
WHAT WE KNOW NOW THERE ARE TWO
SEPARATE CRIME SCENES, ONE IN
NEW JERSEY WHY HIS FATHER
APPEARS TO BE KILLED BY HIM.
AS WELL AS A CRIME SCENE, TWO
CRIME SCENES IN CONNECTICUT, ONE
AT THE SCHOOL AND ONE IN HIS
MOTHER'S HOME.
SO LAW ENFORCEMENT HAS A VERY
BIG TASK, PUTTING TOGETHER THE
DIFFERENT CRIME SCENES AND TIE
THE CASE TOGETHER TO UNDERSTAND
WHY IT HAPPENED, WERE THERE
WARNING SIGNS, AND WHAT DO WE DO
MOVING FORWARD.
TO JEFF'S POINT, I WOULD SAY IT
IS TIME FOR US TO GO HIM AND HUG
OUR CHILDREN AND TO BE WITH OUR
CHILDREN AND TRY AND COUNSEL
THEM IN WHAT HAPPENED IN SOMEONE
ELSE'S SCHOOL BUS THEY WILL HEAR
ABOUT IT.
>> I AM GLAD YOU BROUGHT THAT
UP.
WE WILL TAKE A QUICK BREAK BUT
SO MANY PARENTS AND FAMILIES ARE
GOING TO SEE THIS, IT IS
UNAVOIDABLE, SO WE WILL LEARN TO
TALK TO OUR KIDS ABOUT IT.
DO YOU WANT TO TAKE A BREAK?
WE WILL TAKE A QUICK BREAK.
>> WE EXPECT TO HEAR FROM THE
GOVERNOR OF CUT -- CONNECTICUT
WHERE THE SCHOOL SHOOTING TOOK
PLACE THIS DAY, RIGHT BEFORE
HOLIDAY BREAK IN THE MIDDLE OF
HANUKAH RIGHT BEFORE CHRISTMAS.
WE EXPECT TO HEAR FROM GOVERNOR
MALLOY IN A FEW MINUTES AND HOPE
TO HEAR MORE OF THE DETAILS.
OFFICIALS HAVE BEEN KEEPING THE
DETAILS UNDER WRAPS.
THEY ARE TALKING TO THE FAMILIES
OF THOSE AFFECTED.
WELCOME BACK TO CONTINUING
COVERAGE OF THE WORST SCHOOL
SHOOTINGS IN OUR HISTORY.
26 PEOPLE PLUS THE SHOOTER ARE
DEAD.
20 OF THEM, THE VICTIMS, ARE
CHILDREN.
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT; WHERE
THIS HAPPENED.
TEACHERS AND SCHOOL OFFICIALS
HELPED THE YOUNG STUDENTS
ESCAPE.
THE FIREHOUSE WAS DOWN THE BLOCK
AND THEY TOLD THEM TO CLOSE
THEIR EYES AS THEY LEFT THE
SCHOOL BUILDING.
MOMENTS AGO THE PRESIDENT
OFFERED HIS THOUGHTS FROM THE
WHITE HOUSE.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF FIVE AND TEN.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM: BIRTHDAYS,
GRADUATIONS, WEDDINGS, KIDS OF
THEIR OWN.
>> THE MURDER OF THE CHILDREN
AND THE DEATH OF THEIR DREAMS.
>> SOME OF THE KIDS ARE BEING
LED OUT OF THE SCHOOL AND THE
GIRL IN THE CENTER OF THE SCREEN
IS CRYING BEYOND CONSOLABLE
GETTING LED OUT OF SCHOOL.
THE HOSPITAL IN NEIGHBORING
DANBURY CONNECTICUT IS TREATING
THREE PATIENT.
THE SCHOOL AND THE FACILITY WAS
ON LOCKDOWN.
WE SPOKE WITH THE MAYOR OF
DANBURY WHO SAID THE COMMUNITIES
HAD ACTIONS PLANS IN PLACE.
>> WHETHER IT WAS A SCHOOL
SHOOTER OR MASS CASUALTY WE
DRILL AND WE PRACTICE AND THE
KIDS PRACTICE.
THAT IS WHY WE NEED THESE THINGS
SO WE ARE READY.
>> WE SPOKE WITH AN 8-YEAR-OLD
WOULD CAME OUT OF SCHOOL 10
MINUTES AGO AND SAID SHE
REMEMBERS FIRE DRILLS AND WE
KNOW A DRILL IS ONE THING BUT A
MASS SHOOTING IS ANOTHER.
LITTLE CAN PREPARE YOU FOR THIS.
THE PARENTS HAVE BEEN STUNNED
SAYING THEY HAVE KNOWN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AS ONE OF THE
SAFEST PLACES IN THE COUNTRY.
RICK?
Rick: WE ARE SURROUNDED BY
DOZENS OF MEMBERS OF THE MEDIA.
THE GOVERNOR IS VERY CLOSE AND
IS EXPECTED TO APPROACH THE
PODIUM.
I WANT TO UPDATE OUR VIEWERS ON
INFORMATION FROM A RELIABLE
FEDERAL LAW ENFORCEMENT SOURCE
WHO SAYS THE SHOOTER IN THIS
CASE MAY NOT BE RYAN LANZA BUT
HIS BROTHER.
RYAN LANZA IS IN CUSTODY IN NEW
JERSEY AND THAT ADAM, 20, IS, IN
FACT, THE SHOOTER AND USED AN
ASSAULT RIFLE AND A GLOCK
HANDGUN AND MAY HAVE KILLED HIS
FATHER IN NEW JERSEY AND THEN
GONE DO HIS MOTHER'S HOME HERE
NEAR SANDY HOOK IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, KILLED HIS MOTHER
AND WENT TO HER KINDERGARTEN AND
SLAUGHTERED EVERY CHILD IN THE
CLASSROOM.
THE DEATH TOLL IS 26 INCLUDING
20 CHILDREN AND FIVE ADULTS.
THE SHOOTER IS CONFIRMED DEAD
AND IS, IN FACT, ADAM LANZA AND
HIS BROTHER, RYAN, MAY BE IN
CUSTODY.
I AM TOLD THE TWO WEAPONS WERE
REGISTERED TO HIS MOTHER.
WE ARE EXPECTING AN UPDATE FROM
THE GOVERNOR.
WE WERE TOLD EARLIER THAT HIS
PRIMARY CONCERN IS THE FAMILY
MEMBERS OF THE VICTIMS AND THE
GOVERNOR'S PRESS PERSON IS
APPROACHING AS OUR THE STATE
POLICE.
>> THANK YOU.
WE WILL GO THERE LIKE TO THE LOT
OF THE SCENE ARE PARENTS AND AN
OFFICIAL AND WE DON'T KNOW THE
WOMAN ON LEFT.
MAYBE WE CAN BRING THAT PICTURE
BACK, SOMEONE WHO IS REACTING TO
THE SITUATION LOOKING BEYOND
CONSOLABLE AND WE CAN ONLY
IMAGINE AS WE LEARN 20 CHILDREN
DEAD, SEVERAL ADULTS, AND WE ARE
STILL WAITING ON CONSOLATION ON
WHAT HAPPENED INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
RICK BROUGHT US NEWS THAT
PERHAPS THE NAME THAT WE HAVE
FOR THE INDIVIDUAL OF THE
SHOOTER IS WRONG AND WE WILL
WORK ON CONFIRMING THAT.
RICK IS ALWAYS RELIABLE AND THIS
HAS BEEN CHAOS.
THIS ONLY THE INITIAL REPORTS
POINTED TO TWO SHOOTERS.
WE ALSO HEARD THAT LOCAL
OFFICIALS WERE LOOKING FOR
ANOTHER CAR THAT HAD FLED THE
SCENE.
WE HAD LIVE SHOTS OF
INVESTIGATORS GOING INTO THE
WOODS BEHIND THE SCHOOLS.
THERE WERE MANY QUESTIONS ON
WHETHER THE INVESTIGATION WAS
OVER, WAS THE SCENE DONE, OR WAS
THERE SOMETHING GOING ON.
OBVIOUSLY THERE IS MUCH MORE TO
THE INVESTIGATION.
THE BODY OF THE SHOOTER IS
INSIDE THE BILL AND WE WILL WORK
ON CONFIRMING THE IDENTITY.
ONE OF THE THING WE ARE ALSO
WATCHING IS THE FACT THAT
WHOEVER THE SHOOTER IS, THE
BROTHER, TRY AS WE MAY, RYAN OR
ADAM -- HERE IS THE GOVERNOR.
>> TRAGEDY PLAYED ITSELF OUT IN
THIS COMMUNITY.
THE LT. GOVERNOR AND I HAVE BEEN
SPOKEN TO IN AN ATTEMPT TO BE
PREPARED FOR SOMETHING LIKE THIS
PLAYING ITSELF OUT.
WE CAN NEVER BE PREPARED IF THIS
KIND OF INCIDENT.
WHAT HAS HAPPENED, WHAT HAS
TRANSPIRED AT THE SCHOOL
BUILDING WILL LEAVE A MARK ON
THIS COMMUNITY AND EVERY FAMILY
IMPACTED.
I AND ONLY THAT ALL OF OUR
FELLOW CITIZENS IN THE UNITED
STATES AND AROUND THE WORLD WHO
HAVE OFFERED THEIR ASSISTANCE,
REMEMBER ALL OF THE VICTIMS IN
THEIR PRAYERS.
TO ALL OF YOU OF THE MEDIA, WE
WILL DO OUR BEST TO KEEP YOU AS
INFORMED AS WE CAN.
AFTER I'M DONE SPEAKING A
REPRESENTATIVE OF THE STATE
POLICE WILL SPEAK TO YOU AND
GIVE YOU SOME ADDITIONAL
INFORMATION.
EARLY TODAY A NUMBER OF OUR
CITIZENS, BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN,
HAD THEIR LIVE TAKEN AWAY FROM
THEM, AS WELL AS ADULTS WHOSE
RESPONSIBILITY IT WAS TO EDUCATE
AND SUPERVISE THOSE CHILDREN.
THE PERPETRATOR OF THE CRIME IS
DEAD AS IS AN INDIVIDUAL WHO THE
PERPETRATOR LIVED WITH.
WITH THAT I WILL TURN IT OVER TO
PAUL WHO WILL ANSWER OR WILL
GIVE YOU ADDITIONAL INFORMATION.
LATER IN THE DAY, PERHAPS, WE
WILL SPEAK AGAIN.
ON BEHALF OF THE PEOPLE OF THE
STATE OF CONNECTICUT WE EXTEND
OUR CONDOLENCES TO THE PARENTS
OF THESE CHILDREN AS WELL AS THE
ADULTS.
I THANK THE PRESIDENT WHO HAS
BEEN ON THE PHONE WITH US TODAY
FOR HIS STATEMENT RELEASED TO
YOU A LITTLE WHILE AGO AND THE
STATEMENT MADE TO ME EARLIER
TODAY AS THE HOURS RACED BY.
I SHOULD ALSO SAY THERE ARE A
NUMBER OF PUBLIC OFFICIALS
INCLUDING THE FIRST SELECT WOMAN
WHO HAS BEEN ON-SITE THROUGHOUT
THE DAY.
WE HAVE STATE REPRESENTATIVE AND
STATE SENATOR AND OTHER SELECT
PEOPLE WHO ARE HERE.
WE HAVE THE SUPERINTENDENT OF
SCHOOLS WOULD HAS DONE WONDERFUL
WORK IN HELPING US GET THE
INFORMATION NECESSARY TO BEGIN
THE PROCESS THAT WILL BE ONGOING
FOR A NUMBER OF HOURS.
I THANK IN ADVANCE THE SENATORS
FOR ALSO JOINING US.
I WILL ABSENT AND MR. VANCE WILL
COME FORWARD AND SPEAK WITH YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> GOOD EVENING.
I WOULD LIKE TO RESTATE SOME
INFORMATION WE MADE AVAILABLE
EARLIER AND WE WILL TAKE SOME
QUESTIONS BUT THIS IS AN ACTIVE
ONGOING INVESTIGATION WITH A
GREAT DEAL OF WORK TO GO AND A
LOT OF THINGS WE CANNOT CONFIRM
OR DISCUSS AS OF YET.
SHORTLY AFTER 9:30 THIS MORNING,
THE POLICE DEPARTMENT RECEIVED A
CALL FOR HELP AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY COOL IN NEWTOWN.
UPON REALIZING THE INTENSITY AND
DIFFICULTY OF THE SITUATION WE
CALLED FOR SURROUNDING POLICE
DEPARTMENTS AND STATE POLICE TO
RESPOND.
UPON ARRIVAL, OFFICERS AT THE
SCHOOL IMMEDIATELY ENTERED THE
SCHOOL AS WE KNEW IT WAS
POTENTIAL ACTIVE SHOOTER
SITUATION.
THE FOCUS WAS TO SEARCH FOR
STUDENTS, FACULTY AND STAFF AND
REMOVE THEM TO A SAFE AREA
OUTSIDE OF THE SCHOOL.
THEY DID SEARCH EVERY NOOK AND
CRANNY EVERY ROOM, AND EVERY
PORTION OF THAT SCHOOL AND
ACCOMPLISHED THAT TASK.
THEY TOOK THE RESCUE TO A SAMING
AREA TO REUNITE THEM WITH FAMILY
MEMBERS.
AS HAS BEEN REPORTED THERE WERE
FATALITIES.
THERE WERE 18 CHILDREN
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCHOOL
AND TWO TRANSPORTED TO AREA
HOSPITALS AND PRONOUNCED DEAD AT
AREA HOSPITALS AND THERE WERE
SIX ADULTS PRONOUNCED DEAD AT
THE SCENE AT THE SCHOOL.
AS THE GOVERNOR REPORTED, THE
SHOOTER IS DECEASED AND DECEASED
IN THE SCHOOL.
THERE IS A GREAT DEAL OF WORK
GOING ON RELATIVE TO THAT.
THAT I WE HAVE NOT
IDENTIFIED HIM.
THAT MEANS SEARCH WARRANTS AND
EXAMINATIONS OF RESIDENCE,
EMPLOYMENT, AND OTHER ANCILLARY
THINGS.
THE SCENE HAS BEEN SECURED.
NEWTOWN POLICE OFFICERS, STATE
POLICE MAJOR CRIME UNITS FOR
WESTERN DISTRICT AND CENTRAL
DISTRICT HAVE RESPONDED AND ARE
WORKING WITH SEVERAL AGENCIES TO
PROCESS THIS SCENE.
IT IS NOT A SIMPLISTIC SCENE.
WE NEED TO ESTABLISH IDENTITY.
WE NEED TO DOCUMENT THE ENTIRE
SCENE.
WE NEED TO ANSWER EVERY SINGLE
QUESTION SURROUNDING EXACTLY HOW
AND WHY THIS INCIDENT OCCURRED.
AS THE GOVERNOR SAID WE WILL BE
HERE THROUGH THE NIGHT,
CERTAINLY THROUGH THE WEEKEND
AND WE ARE NOT PUTTING A TIME
STAMP ON COMPLETION.
WE WILL WORK WITH THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER AND ESTABLISH POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATION L IS A GREAT DEAL
OF WORK THAT NEEDS TO BE DONE.
WE WILL TAKE VERY BRIEF
QUESTIONS.
THIS IS AN ACTIVE ONGOING
SITUATION.
>> WE ARE TOLD THERE ARE TWO
OTHER CRIME SCENES?
>> THERE IS A SECONDARY CRIME
SCENE IN NEWTOWN, THAT IS
CORRECT.
THERE IS AN ADULT DECEASED AT
THAT LOCATION.
I CANNOT DISCUSS ANYMORE
INFORMATION ON THAT.
THERE IS ASSISTANCE BEING LENDED
TO US BY NEW JERSEY.
I DON'T HAVE THE DETAILS.
(INAUDIBLE).
>> I CAN STATE THE INFORMATION
WE HAVE RIGHT NOW THE SHOOTINGS
TOOK PLACE IN ONE SECTION OF THE
SCHOOL IN TWO ROOMS.
THAT AS MUCH AS WE WILL GO IN AS
FAR AS LOCATION.
OUR PERSONNEL ARE DOCUMENTING
THE ENTIRE SCENE.
WE WILL HAVE EVERYTHING MAPPED
OUT IN A FINAL REPORT WITH FINAL
INFORMATION PRESENTING THE
ANSWERS.
RIGHT NOW I DON'T HAVE ANYMORE
DETAILS.
RIGHT NOW THERE IS ONE SHOOTER
BUT WE ARE STILL LOOKING AT
EVERY ANSWER LATER FACT AND
CIRCUMSTANCE RELATED TO THE
DECEASED SHOOTER AT THE SCENE.
>> DID THE SHOOTER TAKE HIS
LIFE?
>> TO BE DETERMINED.
WHY HAVE THE ANSWER, THE NEXT
STEP IS THE MEDICAL EXAMINER'S
OFFICE WHO WILL ASSIST US IN
ANSWERING THE MANY AND CAUSE OF
DEATH.
>> HOW MANY INJURED?
>> THAT IS IT, 26 DECEASED.
>> NO INJURIES?
>> ONE PERSON INJUREED.
>> WERE THE CHILDREN IN ONE
CLASSROOM?
>> IN ONE SECTION.
ONE AREA.
I DON'T KNOW SPECIFICALLY HOW
MANY ROOMS ARE INVOLVED.
I WAS TOLD THERE WERE TWO BUT
ONE SECTION OF THE BUILDING.
EVERYONE WAS IN THAT SAME
SECTION OF THE BUILDING.
THE SECTION OF THE BUILDING
EXACTLY IS TO BE DETERMINED.
>> DID YOU SAY HOW THE SHOOTER
DIED?
>> THAT IS TO BE DETERMINED WHEN
THE EXAMINATIONS ARE COMPLETE.
>> 26 INCLUDING THE SHOOTER?
>> 20 CHILDREN, SIX ADULTS AND
THE SHOOTER.
27 TOTAL.
(INAUDIBLE).
>> AND THAT IS THE SCHOOL AND A
SECONDARY CRIME SCENE A DECEASED
ADULT.
(INAUDIBLE).
>> TO BE DETERMINED.
OUR INVESTIGATORS ARE LOOK AT
THAT.
WE HAVE NOT MADE ANY POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATION.
THERE IS PRELIMINARY
IDENTIFICATION BUT WE HAVE A
GREAT DEAL OF WORK.
THAT IS SOMETHING WE HAVE TO DO
IS ESTABLISH POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATION ON ALL THE
DECEASED, A TIME
WAS THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER
INJURED?
>> THAT, I DON'T KNOW.
IT WAS 20 CHILDREN, SIX ADULTS,
AND THE THE SHEAR, AND A
SECONDARY SCENE WITH AN ADULT
VICTIM AT THAT SCENE.
THE NEXT UPDATE WILL ENABOUT
QUARTER TO 5:00.
THAT WILL BE AN UPDATE.
>> ONE THING I WOULD LIKE TO
SAY, WE HAVE BEEN MEETING WITH
ALL OF THE FAMILY MEMBERS.
IT IS A VERY, VERY DIFFICULT
SCENE FOR THE FAMILY MEMBERS,
AND ALL THE RESPONDING FIRST
RESPONDERS.
IT IS A TRAGIC STATE.
WE HAVE BEEN ASKED BY THE FAMILY
MEMBERS TO ASK THE MEMBERS OF
THE PRESS TO REQUEST THEIR
PRIVACY AND TO, PLAZA, LEAVE
THEY ARE GOING THROUGH A
TREMENDOUS AMOUNT OF GROWTH.
I AM SURE YOU CAN APPRECIATE
THAT.
I HAVE BEEN ASKED TO ASK YOU
THAT PERSONALLY.
BACK IN 60 MINUTES TO ASK
ADDITIONAL QUESTIONS.
>> THAT IS LIEUTENANT PAUL
ADVANCE, THE FIRST TIME HE HAS
ANSWERED QUESTIONS ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED EARLY THIS MORNING AT
SANDY HOOK LTY SCHOOL.
WE HAVE NEW NOW A LIKE SHOT OF
WHAT WE BELIEVE TO BE THE HOME
OF THE SHOOTER.
RICK BROUGHT US THE NEWS OF THE
IDENTITY OF THE SHOOTER MAYBE
BEING ADAM LANZA OR RYAN LANZA.
WE ARE TRYING TO WORK THROUGH
THAT.
A LOT OF CONFLICTING REPORTS
WHICH SON OF THE FAMILY IT MIGHT
BE.
THE FATHER WAS FOUND DEAD IN NEW
JERSEY, THE MOTHER FOUND DEAD IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THERE IS STILL QUESTION ON THE
IDENTITY OF SHOOTER.
RICK?
Rick: THE POLICE ARE RELUCTANT
TO GET IN TO TOO MANY DETAILS OF
THE SHOOTING, THEY ARE WORKING
TO IDENTIFY THE VICTIMS IN THE
SCHOOL AND ARE NOT READY TO
IDENTIFY THE SHOOTER.
I GOT THAT INFORMATION FROM A
RELIABLE LAW ENFORCEMENT SOURCE.
WE HEARD THIS FAMILY WAS
INVOLVED AND THE SHOTTER HAD A
BROTHER AND NOW WE TOLD THE
SHOOTER'S BROTHER COULD BE IN
CUSTODY AND THE SHOOTER
OBVIOUSLY KILLED HIMSELF DURING
THE NEWS CONFERENCE WE HEARD.
WE ARE NOW CONFIRMING THE
NUMBERS WHICH ARE STAGGERING AND
HORRIFIC: 20 CHILDREN KILLED.
18 DEAD INSIDE THE SCHOOL AND
TWO TRANSPORTED DYING IN THE
HOSPITAL.
SIX ADULTS INCLUDING THE SHOOTER
DEAD IN THE SCHOOL.
AND CONFIRMED A SECOND CRIME
SCENE HERE IN NEWTOWN, THE HOME
BELONGING TO THE MOTHER OF THE
SHOOTER.
THE MOTHER BELIEVED TO BE DEAD
INSIDE THE HOME.
WE ARE TOLD THE KINDERGARTEN
CLASS THAT WAS ASSAULTED WAS THE
CHOOSE OF THE MOTHER.
SHE WAS A KINDERGARTEN TEACHER
SO A HORRIFIC SET OF
CIRCUMSTANCES.
POLICE HAVE A LONG ROAD AHEAD OF
THEM, PROCESSING THAT CHRISTMAS
SCENE AND PUTTING THIS TOGETHER.
>> ONE THING WE HEARD FROM
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE, HE WAS
ASKED WHEN THE POLICE WENT TO
THE SCHOOL WAS IT LIKE, DID THE
POLICE ENGAGE WITH THE SHOOTER
AND WE LEARNED ACCORDING TO LT.
COLONEL, POLICE DID NOT SHOOT
THE SHOOTER.
THE SHOOTER IS DEAD.
SO WE CAN NEVER, ALTHOUGH WE
WILL WAIT IF CONFIRMATION, HE
TOOK HIS OWN LIFE.
WE HAVE STATE REPRESENTATIVE
JOHN FRY OF CONNECTICUT.
REPRESENTATIVE, YOU HAVE TWO
NIECES AND A REVENUE IN THE
SCHOOL -- A NEPHEW.
ARE THEY OKAY?
>>Guest: THANKFULLY.
MY NIECE, THE TWINS, ARE IN
4th, SO THEY WILL BE TEN IN
FEBRUARY.
AND MY NEPHEW IS IN 1st.
>> DID THEY SEE ANYTHING?
>>Guest: THEY DID NOT.
MY NIECES WERE IN THE LIBRARY
AND THE LIBRARIAN AND TEACH ARE
PUT THEM IN A CLOSET.
MY NEPHEW WAS IN A CLASSROOM
CLOSE TO THE CLASSROOM WHERE
MOST OF THE VICTIMS BUT NO ONE
SAW ANYTHING.
LEAVING THEY SCHOOL THEY SAW
BROKEN GLASS AND THE POLICE AND
SWAT TEAMS BUT THEY ALSO HEARD
NOISE BUT THEY DIDN'T SEE
ANYTHING.
>> SOME OF THE KIN DESCRIBED
NOISE AS "POTS BANGING AROUND"
OR HAMMERS.
ONE 8-YEAR-OLD SAID SHE THOUGHT
IT WAS HAMMERS AND THAT IS WHAT
THE TEACHER TOLD THEM.
DO YOU HAVE ANY INDICATION THAT
EITHER YOUR NIECES OR YOUR
NEPHEW KNEW THE CHILDREN HURT
TOGETHER.
>>Guest: FIRST, MY
UNDERSTANDING IS THERE WAS AN
ALTERCATION IN THE SCHOOL OFFICE
AND SOMEONE IN THE OFFICE HAD
THE FORESITE TO PUT THE AUDIO
SWITCH THAT SIGNALS TO THE
SCHOOL THERE WAS SOMETHING GOING
ON SO LIKE EVERYONE ELSE IN THE
SCHOOL MY NIECES AND NEPHEWS
HEARD A COMMOTION FOR A BRIEF
MOMENT.
NO INDICATION YET BUT LAST NIGHT
I WAS AT THE SANDY HOOK HOLIDAY
CONCERT WHERE THE 4th GRADERS
PARTICIPATE AND I CANNOT GO PACK
AND THINK OF THE PEOPLE IN THE
AUDIENCE AND THE YOUNGER KIDS
RUNNING UP-AND-DOWN THE AISLES
AND THEY HAVE ALL BEEN...THINGS
ARE DIFFERENT TODAY FOR THE
PEOPLE IN THE AUDITORIUM.
>> THANK YOU FOR SHARING THAT
WITH YOU.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] WHILE YOU'RE
GETTING READY FOR THE HOLIDAYS,
WE'RE GETTING READY FOR YOU.
TIS THE SEASON.
FOR FOOD, FOR FAMILY,
AND NOW, SOMETHING EXTRA --
FOR YOU.
>> CONTINUING COVERAGE OVER A
MASSACRE AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IN CONNECTICUT.
THE GUNMAN'S MOTHER WORKED AT
THE SCHOOL AND PRESUMED DEAD.
HIS FATHER IS DEAD.
WE OBVIOUSLY KNOW THE SUSPECT IS
DEAD WITH HIS BODY STILL INSIDE
THE SCHOOL.
THIS IS A LIVE SHOT OF HOBOKEN,
NEW JERSEY, WHERE WE BELIEVE THE
SHOOTER LIVED AND WHERE THE
FATHER'S BODY IS, WE BELIEVE.
THE SHOOTER TOOK THE LIVES OF 20
CHILDREN AND MANY ADULTS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA ORDERING INS TO
FLY AT HALF STAFF.
IN THE MEANTIME SOURCES TELLING
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS THE
SUSPECTED SHOOTER'S GIRLFRIEND
AND ANOTHER FRIEND ARE MISSING
AND THAT HIS BROTHER IS BEING
HELD AS A POSSIBLE SECOND
SHOOTER.
MOLLY HAS MORE.
>> I AM AT A SECONDARY SCENE THE
AUTHORITIES HAVE TALKED ABOUT,
IN THE COMMUNITY WHERE THE HOME
OF THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER IS,
NANCY, WHO HAS BEEN CONFIRMED
DEAD.
THERE IS ONE BODY IN THE HOME.
AUTHORITIES CONTINUE TO HAVE
THIS NEIGHBORHOOD BLOCKED DOWN
AND YOU CAN SEE THE YELLOW TAPE
HERE.
BEFORE WE CAME HERE WE GOT OUT
IN THE SANDY HOOK COMMUNITY, THE
PEOPLE THAT SURROUND THAT
SCHOOL, THE BUSINESSES, AND AS
YOU CAN IMAGINE THEY ARE JUST
GOING TO COME TO GRIPS WITH THE
PAIN THEY WILL FEEL IN THE
COMING DAYS PARTICULARLY WITH
THE NUMBERS CONFIRMED THAT 20
CHILDREN ARE DEAD.
WE HAD A CHANCE TO SPEAK WITH A
NUMBER OF THE BUSINESS OWNERS, A
CAFE OWNER WHO SAW EVERYONE IN
THE CAFE, MANY MOTHERS IN THE
MORNING RUNNING FOR THE SCHOOL,
AND WE HAD A CHANCE TO SPEAK
WITH A WOMAN WHO CUTS HAIR IN
THE COMMUNITY.
SHE TALKED ABOUT HER FEARS OF
WHO THE 20 CHILDREN WILL BE AS
EVERYONE WAITS TO FIND OUT THEIR
IDENTITIES AND THE IDENTITIES OF
THE OTHER ADULTS KILLED.
>> 5 TO 10 YEARS OLD IS WHAT WE
KNOW OF THE VICTIMS.
WHO AND WHY THIS HAPPENED ARE
QUESTIONS WE DON'T HAVE ANTIS
FOR.
WE DO EXPECT A NEWS CONFERENCE
FROM LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE IN AN
HOUR.
THAT IS IT FOR "STUDIO B" TODAY
AND HARRIS IS HERE LATER FOR THE
FOX REPORT AT 7:00 P.M. EASTERN
AND CONTINUING COVERAGE HERE ON
FOX NEWS.
What's next?
He's going to apply testosterone
to his underarm.
AXIRON, the only underarm
treatment for low T,
can restore testosterone levels
back to normal in most men.
AXIRON is not for use in women
or anyone younger than 18.
AXIRON can transfer to
others through direct contact.
Women, especially those who are
or who may become pregnant,
and children should avoid
contact where AXIRON is applied
as unexpected signs of puberty
in children or changes
in body hair or increased
acne in women may ocr.
Report these signs and symptoms
to your doctor if they occur.
Tell your doctor about
all medical conditions
and medications.
Do not use if you have prostate
or breast cancer.
Serious side effects
could include
increased risk
of prostate cancer;
worsening prostate symptoms;
decreased sperm count;
ankle, feet, or body swelling;
enlarged or painful breasts;
problems breathing while
sleeping;
and blood clots in the legs.
Common side effects include
skin redness
or irritation where applied,
increased
red blood cell count,
headache, diarrhea, vomiting,
and increase in PSA.
See your doctor,
and for a 30-day free trial,
go to Axiron.com.