>> Greg: HELLO, I'M GREG
GUTFELD WITH ANDREA TANTAROS,
BOB BECKEL, ERIC BOLLING, DANA
PERINO.
IT'S 5:00 IN NEW YORK CITY.
THIS IS "THE FIVE."
♪
SO IN TIMES OF TRAGEDY, I KNOW
THAT OPINIONS OR FACTS DON'T
HELP THE SUFFERING.
SAYING GUN VIOLENCE DROPPED
OVER 40 YEARS OR SCHOOLS ARE
SAFER THAN EVER, THAT MEANS
VERY IT WILL TO PEOPLE IN
SHOCK.
IT'S JUST NOISE.
TO ME, IT'S LIKE GUN FREE
ZONES.
IT SOUNDS GREAT BUT ONLY IN
MEDIA WHO WORKS IN GUN
PROTECTED ZONES.
FORT HOOD, THE DEAD WEREN'T
CHILDREN BUT THEY WERE
WARRIORS, KILLED IN A GUN FREE
ZONE IN ARMY BASE.
YOU THINK THE COWARD HASAN
DIDN'T KNOW THAT.
EVIL SEEKS THE VULNERABLE.
SO WHY CAN'T A SCHOOL BE
PROTECTED AS 30 ROCK?
IS A TALKING HEAD MORE
VALUABLE THAN A CHILD?
WHAT DO I KNOW?
I'M A TALKING HEAD.
I KNOW NOTHING.
AS RARE AS THE HORRIBLE EVENTS
ARE, EVIL WILL ALWAYS BE.
ADDRESSING MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES HELP, AS WE FEEL AS THE
EVIL.
EACH CREEP HAS THE SAME M.O.
BUT WE REPORT IT LIKE IT'S
NEW.
MAYBE IT'S TIME TO PONDER
INSTEAD OF PONTIFICATE.
NOBODY IS LISTENING.
THEY HEARD IT BEFORE.
TRAGICALLY, WE HEAR IT ALL
AGAIN.
SO THIS SEEMS LIKE WE
REPSYCHOTHE SAME ARGUMENT WHEN
THIS HAPPENS.
IS IT GOING TO BE US VERSUS
THEM?
>> THIS ONE MIGHT BE
DIFFERENT.
I THINK THAT THE INNOCENCE OF
THE LIVES TAKEN, THE YOUNG
TENDERNESS OF THE AGE MADE
PEOPLE THINK WHAT CAN WE DO?
ASIDE FROM SOME PLACES WHERE
THE TALK IS ONLY ABOUT GUN
CONTROL, THERE HAS BEEN A
SENSE OF ANXIETY ABOUT WHAT WE
ARE NOT DOING TO HELP PROVIDE
FOR FAMILIES THAT HAVE A LOVED
ONE THAT IS MENTALLY ILL AND
NEEDS SERIOUS HELP BEFORE THEY
DO HARM TO NOBODY ELSE.
THIS ONE COULD BE DIFFERENT.
THERE MIGHT BE SOMETHING WE
CAN DO.
TO HELP PREVENT IT FROM
HAPPENING AGAIN.
>> IT SEEMS LIKE WE ARE
TALKING ABOUT DIFFERENT
VARIABLES TO MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES TO SCHOOL SECURITY, TO
GUN CONTROL PREVIOUSLY WE ONLY
FOCUSED ON GUN CONTROL.
DOES IT MEAN THERE IS
PROGRESS?
>> Andrea: I DON'T KNOW.
AS HOPEFUL THAT I AM THAT DANA
IS RIGHT IT SEEMS WE HAVE ONE
SIDE SHOUTING THEIR POINT.
THE OTHER SIDE SHOUTING THEIR
POINT.
YOU COMEDIANS MAKING FUN OF
ONE SIDE, USUALLY CON
SEVENTIVES FOR TRYING TO
DEFEND THEIR POINT.
THERE SHOULD BE A WAITING
PERIOD.
THERE NEEDS TO BE TIME BEFORE
EVERYBODY JUMPS UP AND DOWN
ABOUT THIS.
SONG IS THERE TO DO A LOT OF
THINGS.
NOT JUST HANDLE THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
THIS IS AN OPPORTUNITY FOR
CONGRESS.
IT NEVER HAPPENS.
SOMEONE SAYS THIS IS A GREAT
OPPORTUNITY TO TALK ABOUT
MENTAL ILLNESS, THEN WE MOVE
TO GUN CONTROL.
I HOPE THIS TIME, I KNOW IT'S
CHRISTMAS TIME BUT I HOPE
WEEKS FOLLOWING UP TO THE NEW
YEAR PEOPLE WILL START TO HAVE
A DISCUSSION.
LISTEN, NOT YELL AT THE OTHER
SIDE.
>> Greg: YOU TALK ABOUT
GUNS, MENTAL ILLNESS AND
ALCOHOLISM, AND HOW THERE
SHOULD BE A SCREENING.
DO YOU THINK BECAUSE WE USE
GENERAL ILLNESS THE TOPIC
GENERALLY THAT IT SPREADS SO
THIN WE DON'T CATCH THE PEOPLE
THAT NEED HELP?
>> IN THIS INSTANCE, THE TOPIC
OF MENTAL HEALTH HAS BEEN MORE
PREVALENT THAN BEFORE.
GUN CONTROL, I AM ONE THAT
PUSHED THAT HARD.
BUT THE MENTAL HEALTH QUESTION
IS SERIOUS AND REAL.
WE KNOW THAT THE FUNDS ARE CUT
BACK IN THE STATE.
LOCAL AND THE FEDERAL LEVEL
FOR THAT.
THEY BE PART AND PARCEL.
THIS IS A TIME PEOPLE START TO
RAISE QUESTIONS ABOUT THE
VIDEO GAMES AND THE WAY PEOPLE
COMMUNICATE.
SO MAYBE THIS IS A BROADER
CONVERSATION.
HOW THAT IS TANG SEASONABLE
SOMETHING I HAVE A HARD TIME
FIGURING THAT OUT.
>> Greg: EVERYBODY DOES.
WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF THIS?
I LOOK AT THIS AND THERE IS
ONE LINKAGE TO THE CATASTROPHE
AS THEY GET MORE AND MORE
GRUESOME, THEY BUILD UP ON
EACH OTHER.
THEY TEND TO INVOLVE THE
LONERS.
I MEAN, YOU KNOW, I DON'T LIKE
TALKING ABOUT THEM BECAUSE TO
ME, THEY ARE LOSERS.
BUT WE CANNOT AVOID THAT.
>> Eric: MADE THE POINT LAST
NIGHT.
NOT GOING TO MENTION THE GUY'S
NAME.
CALL HIM THE SHOOTER.
MADE A POINT LAST NIGHT, I
SAID I DON'T THINK THIS IS THE
TIME OR THE PLACE FOR THE GUN
DISCUSSION.
THIS IS A WHOLE HOST OF
THINGS.
MENTAL HEALTH, VIDEO GAMES.
THE CULTURE AROUND WHAT THE
CHILDREN ARE BROUGHT, THE WAY
THE CHILDREN ARE BROUGHT UP
THAT THE VIOLENCE IS OKAY.
BLOW AWAY PEOPLE OR DO IT ON
TV OR A VIDEO GAME, IT'S
RELIGION.
BREAKDOWN OF THE FAMILY VALUE.
NUCLEAR FAMILY.
A HOST OF THINGS THERE.
HAS TO BE MEANINGFUL
DISCUSSION, NOT ALL OF IT
INCLUDING GUNS, I JUST CAN'T
DO IT RIGHT NOW.
TWO MORE BURIALS GOING ON
TODAY.
WHEN WE ARE THROUGH WITH THESE
THINGS AND IT'S TIME TO MOVE
ON TO THE DISCUSSION.
BOB AND I AND YOU, THE LEFT
WILL HAVE A MASSIVE DISCUSSION
OVER WHAT IS RIGHT.
WHETHER THE SECOND AMENDMENT
SHOULD STAY INTACT.
>> Bob: ONE THING WE AGREE
ON IS THE SCHOOLS COULD USE
PROTECTION.
IF YOU PUT ONE POLICEMAN ON
EVERY SCHOOL, $56,000 ON
AVERAGE TO PUT THEM IN THERE,
WHERE DO THE RESOURCES COME
FROM?
>> Eric: I BROUGHT THIS UP
LAST NIGHT.
WE PROTECT MONEY.
BANK PROS TEXT THE MONEY --
PROTECT MONEY MORE THAN THE
CHILDREN.
IT CAN'T BE A FEDERAL SOURCE,
BECAUSE IF YOU PUT FEDERAL
AGENTS IN THE SCHOOL, IT LOOKS
BAD.
THEY WILL SAY WHY ARE YOU
DOING THIS?
PRESIDENT OBAMA WHY ARE YOU
IT HAS TO BE THE STATE LEVEL.
NEWS TODAY, GOVERNOR DONALD IN
VIRGINIA SAID HE IS LOOKING IN
TO THE STATE LEVEL PUTTING
SOCIAL TRAINING OFFICER AT THE
SCHOOLS.
THAT IS THE WAY TO GO.
>> Greg: FREEDOM COSTS
MONEY.
FOR OUR FREEDOM, YOU KNOW, WE
HAVE TO -- AT THE STATE AND
LOCAL LEVEL IT'S WORTH IT.
>> Andrea: WE DID IT
ENPLANES AFTER 9/11.
THERE WAS TALK ABOUT SECRET
AIR MARSHALLS.
THIS SCHOOL WAS EXTREMELY
SECURE AND YOU HAD TO BE
BUZZED IN WHEN YOU GOT IN.
A LOT OF SCHOOLS HAVE METAL
DETECTORS.
I DO HOPE THAT MAYBE THE
DISCUSSION ON MENTAL ILLNESS
IS LESS STIGMATIZING.
YOU READ BLOGS ABOUT I AM
SHOOTER'S MOTHER.
DID HE HAVE ASPERGER.
WAS HE ON THE AUTISM SPECTRUM?
WHATEVER THE CASE, THERE
MOTHER KNEW THERE WAS
SOMETHING WRONG.
HE WAS BURNING HIMSELF.
PUT YOURSELF IN THE SHOES OF
THAT MONEY.
VERY STIGMATIZING FOR HER AND
THE SHOOTER.
TO HANDLE THAT.
NO MOTHER WANTS TO RAT OUT HER
SON.
>> Andrea: THERE ARE EVENTS,
NOT SPECIFICALLY THESE THINGS
LIKE THE AURORA, COLORADO
THING, THAT THE LAW
ENFORCEMENT HATE TO DISCUSS
FOR FEAR OF COPYCAT.
SUICIDAL EVENTS THEY DON'T
BRING UP BECAUSE IT FOSTERS
SUICIDAL THOUGHTS IN OTHER
KIDS.
ARE WE CULPABLE THAT WE DELVE
IN DETAILS OF WHAT THE PERSON
IS, WHEN WE SHOULDN'T.
>> THERE IS A GOOD POINT ABOUT
NOT NAMING THE SHOOTER.
PEOPLE SAID DON'T GLORIFY IT.
HE'S GONE, SO IT DOESN'T HELP
HIM BUT COULD IT HELP SOMEONE
WITH THE TENDENCY OR FEELING
ABOUT TO SNAP TO THINK THIS
COULD BE MY ONE SHOT AT GLORY.
EVEN IF THEY ARE NOT THERE TO
SEE IT.
SO I DON'T KNOW HOW WE DON'T
COVER THE STORY.
TOUGH BALANCE.
>> Bob: ABOUT THE MOTHER,
SOME FACTS WE KNOW.
SHE USED GUNS SHE OWNED THAT
WERE REGISTERED TO HER.
HE SHOT HIS MOTHER AND GUNS
WERE AVAILABLE TO HIM IN THE
HOUSE.
IF YOU KNOW YOU HAVE SOMEONE
DISTURBED AS SHE DID KNOW, WHY
HAVE GUNS AVAILABLE TO HIM IN
THE HOUSE?
>> Bob: A TERRIBLE GUN --
>> Greg: SHE WAS A TERRIBLE
GUN OWNER.
>> Eric: LIKE TIMOTHY
McVEIGH WHO BLEW UP THE
TRUCK WITH FERTILIZER.
>> Andrea: I DON'T WANT TO
BLAME THE MOTHER BECAUSE MAYBE
HE SHOWED NO SIGNS OF THE
ACTUAL VIOLENCE, MAYBE AGAINST
HIMSELF.
PROBABLY THE FURTHEST THOUGHT
FROM HER MIND HE WOULD GO TO
THE GUN CLOSET AND SHOOT
SOMEBODY.
>> THE POLICE OFFICERS WANT TO
UNVALVE THE STORY.
FAMILIES DESERVE IT.
THEY WANT ANSWERS.
SO JUST AS IN THE COLORADO
SHOOTING FOUND OUT MORE ABOUT
IT.
ONE OF THE KEYS SO THAT IS
PEOPLE WHO KNEW HIM, THAT WE
WERE WORRIED ABOUT SOMETHING
HAPPENING.
>> Dana: I HAVEN'T HEARD
THAT ABOUT THIS ONE.
THE COMMUNITY MADE A WIDE
BERTH AROUND THE COMMUNITY AND
THEY WERE ALONE.
NOT THAT THE COMMUNITY WAS
BAD.
BUT IT DOESN'T HAPPEN IN LIFE
YOU TRY TO AVOID THE
SITUATIONS THAT ARE
UNCOMFORTABLE.
NOT A LOT OF SOCIAL
INTERSECTION.
>> Greg: WE HAVE
BREAK.
COMING UP, JOHN BOEHNER AND
PRESIDENT OBAMA MAY BE CLOSED
TO A DEAL ON THE FISCAL CLIFF.
I CAN'T BELIEVE I'M RELIEVED
TO HEAR THAT WORD.
THAT DEBATE IS AHEAD ON "THE
FIVE."
♪
I ALWAYS WAIT
UNTIL THE LAST MINUTE.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME R CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
Meet the 5-passenger
Ford C-MAX Hybrid.
BY DECEMBER 22ND
When you're carrying
a lot of weight,
C-MAX has a nice little trait,
You see, C-MAX helps
you load your freight,
with its foot-activated
lift gate.
But that's not
all you'll see,
Cause C-MAX also
beats Prius v,
with better MPG.
Say hi to the all-new 47
combined MPG C-MAX Hybrid.
>> Andrea: HOUSE SPEAKER
BOEHNER AND PRESIDENT OBAMA
WORKING TO REACH A DEAL TO
STOP ACROSS THE BOARD TAX
INCREASES AND SPENDING CUT AT
THE FIRST OF THE YEAR.
TODAY, SPEAKER BOEHNER
PROPOSED A BACKUP PLAN.
>> I THINK WE ALL KNOW THAT
EVERY INCOME TAX IN AMERICA
WILL PAY A HIGHER RATE IN
JANUARY 1 UNLESS CONGRESS AC
ACTS.
SO I BELIEVE IT'S IMPORTANT TO
PROTECT AS MANY AMERICAN
TAXPAYERS AS WE CAN.
OUR PLAN "B," WOULD PROTECT
THE AMERICAN TAXPAYERS WHO
MAKE $1 MILLION OR LESS.
HAVE ALL THE CURRENT RATES
EXTENDED.
>> Andrea: WELL, THE WHITE
HOUSE PROMPTLY REJECTED IT.
>> THE ALTERNATIVE HERE IF YOU
THINK ABOUT IT WITH THE
SO-CALLED PLAN "B" IT MAKES NO
SENSE.
HISTORIC OPPORTUNITY HERE TO
DO SOMETHING THAT HAS BEEN SET
AS A GOAL TO REACH BIPARTISAN
COMPROMISE ON SIGNIFICANT
DEFICIT REDUCTION ON THE ORDER
OF $4 TRILLION.
TALK ALL THE PIECES OF IT AND
PUT THEM TOGETHER.
WE ARE CLOSE TO BEING ABLE TO
ACHIEVE THAT.
PRESIDENT DEMONSTRATED WITH
OBVIOUS WILLINGNESS TO
COMPROMISE AND TO MOVE MORE
THAN HALFWAY.
>> Andrea: I HAVE TO GO TO
YOU FIRST, DANA BECAUSE YOU
HEARD THE WORDS "OBVIOUSLY."
>> Dana: OBVIOUSLY.
OBVIOUS TERRORISM.
IT'S OBVIOUS!
OBVIOUS.
IF THEY THINK THAT IT'S
OBVIOUS -- I DO THINK THEY
OVERESTIMATE HOW MUCH THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE ARE WILLING TO
WAIT ON THIS.
SPEAKER BOEHNER HAS BASICALLY
WALKED ALL THE WAY OVER TO
THEIR SIDE AND HANDED THEM THE
DEAL THEY ASKED FOR.
SPEAKER BOEHNER IS TAKING
POLITICAL HITS TO GET THE
REPUBLICANS TO COME WITH HIM.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND WHY THE
WHITE HOUSE WOULDN'T POCKET
THIS THING AND SAY THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
MAYBE THEY ASK FOR ONE OF THE
THINGS BUT I'LL TELL YOU WHY.
WHEN PELOSI AND HOYER SAID THE
PLAN "B" WAS A GENENTECHAL
PLOY.
IT WAS THE DEMOCRATIC TALKING
POINT THAT WENT OUT TO
EVERYONE AND EVERYBODY HAD TO
USE IT, THEY ARE MASKING THE
REAL PROBLEM.
THAT HE CANNOT DELIVER
DEMOCRATS ON THE REDUCTION OF
SPENDING.
THE P.R. FRONT.
THE DEMOCRATS MAKE REPUBLICANS
LOOK LIKE THE BAD GUY WHEN
PRESIDENT OBAMA CAN'T DELIVER
HIS OWN PARTY.
>> Bob: NOT CLEAR BOEHNER
CAN DELIVER REPUBLICANS ON
THIS.
>> Dana: BUT DOESN'T OBAMA
HAVE A RESPONSEABILITY TO
BRING DEMOCRATS?
>> Bob: HE DOES.
BOEHNER DOES AS WELL.
BOEHNER SAYS $1 MILLION.
IT WILL END UP IN BETWEEN THE
FIGURES.
IF YOU TAKE IN ACCOUNT WHAT
BOEHNER SAID ABOUT CUTTING,
WHAT HE SAID ABOUT CUTTING THE
TAX LOOPHOLES AND THE SAVINGS
ON MEDICARE AND MEDICAID, THE
TOTAL PACKAGE OF THE SAVINGS,
$4.6 TRILLION.
THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES WASN'T CUT IS $4
$4.6 TRILLION.
>> Andrea: YOU SAID
SOMETHING OFF-CAMERA TO ME.
YOU SAID IF THEY GET SUPPORT
FOR THE TAX NATION, THE
DEMOCRATS HAVE A PROBLEM ON
THEIR HAND.
>> Eric: WHY WOULDN'T?
THEY PROPOSED $1 MILLION.
I THINK THERE WAS 50 SOMETHING
DEMOCRATS WHO SAID YEAH, A
COUPLE HELD OUT BUT YEAH.
MOVING TO 2010.
NOW NO WAY WILL IT FLY.
>> Bob: IT'S NEGOTIATING
PLOY ON EVERYBODY'S PART.
I DON'T THINK BOEHNER THINK HE
IS WILL GET AWAY WITH
$1 BILLION.
IT WILL BE LOWER THAN THAT.
THEY CAN'T TAKE --
>> Eric: HOW DEMOCRATS BRING
IT TO REPUBLICANS TO SAY DO
THIS AND MAKE IT $1 MILLION.
>> Eric: WE MOVE THE
GOALPOST AGAIN.
THE STOCK MARKET KNOWS YOU
WILL GET A DEAL.
BECAUSE IT'S EMINNOCENT.
BUT YOU GET A BAD DEAL FOR
EVERYONE.
>> Andrea: THE REPUBLICANS
MEET BEHIND CLOSED DOORS.
IS HE BOEHNER DARKER TAN?
>> Greg: IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE
SPENDING, NOT TAXES.
LOSING ON THIS SO THIS REMINDS
ME OF 1960 SITCOM ARGUMENT
BETWEEN A MARRIED COUPLE.
BOEHNER IS A SENSIBLE LONG
SUFFERING HUSBAND TRYING TO
TIGHTEN THE PURSE STRINGS.
AND OBAMA IS LUCY RICARDO.
APPRECIATES SPENDING BECAUSE
IT'S FUN, FUN, FUN.
DOESN'T GET THE SAVINGS.
PERHAPS EPISODE OF GREEN
ACRES.
TALKING BIG IS PAUL KRUGMAN.
>> Eric: THE PLAN THAT
BOEHNER OFFERED -- THIS IS
HUGE.
SAID YOU KNOW WHAT?
WE WILL PUT UP THE DEBT
CEILING DEBATE FOR TWO YEARS.
THAT MEANS THE REPUBLICANS, IT
HAS TO GO THROUGH THE HOUSE,
SPENDING BILL COME THROUGH THE
HOUSE.
APPROVED.
THE HOUSE HAS TO APPROVE THE
DEBT CEILING INCES.
THEY SAID THEY PUT IT OFF FOR
TWO YEARS.
HE GAVE PRESIDENT OBAMA THE
BEST GIFT.
THE BEST DEAL THEY COULD DO.
A LOT OF PEOPLE ON THE RIGHT
THINK HE GAVE THEM --
>> Bob: WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
THIS IS NOT THE PELOSI-SCHUMER
PROPOSAL.
WHAT HE IS NOT SAYING THAT THE
REPUBLICANS WILL KEEP IN
CAPITAL GAINS TAX CUTS FOR
EVERYBODY.
NOT DEALT WITH ANY OF THE
OTHER TAX ISSUES INVOLVED IN
THAT BILL.
HE SAID $1 MILLION.
THAT IS IT.
EVERYTHING ELSE STAYS THE
SAME.
EXCEPT FOR PEOPLE OVER
$1 MILLION.
>> Eric: SCHUMER HAD CAPITAL
GAINS RATE LOW.
SCHUMER DEAL.
>> Bob: I DON'T CARE WHAT
SCHUMER DID.
>> Andrea: THIS IS A P.R.
NIGHTMARE FOR BOEHNER.
WE HAVE GREAT REPORTING FROM
CHAD PERGRAM WHO SAID THEY
MIGHT BRING THIS TO THE DEAL
ON THURSDAY, PUT HIM ON
RECORD.
THEN THEY WOULD ONLY HAVE TO
VOTE FOR EXTENDING MIDDLE
CLASS TAX RATES.
THIS SNEAKY.
>> THEY SHOULD BE MAD ON
SPENDING FROM BOTH SIDES.
DOUBLE TRIPLE COUNTING.
IT'S UNCLEAR.
THIS IS A HUGE OPPORTUNITY FOR
AMERICA TO CHANGE COURSE WITH
MAJOR TAX REFORM.
MAJOR ENTITLEMENT REFORM.
THAT IS THE POINT, THE WHOLE
POINT OF THE FISCAL CLIFF TO
PUSH THEM TO TRY TO DO
SOMETHING ON ENTITLEMENT
REFORM.
WHAT ARE WE GETTING?
ZERO ON THAT.
>> Bob: WE ARE GETTING
BOEHNER PLAN "B" THAT TAKES
THE BUSH LEGISLATION TO PUT IT
IN EFFECT --
>> Dana: THAT IS NOT WHAT
THE FISCAL CLIFF WAS ABOUT.
>> Bob: I UNDERSTAND THAT.
>> Dana: THAT IS WHAT I'M
SAYING IT'S A HUGE MISSED
OPPORTUNITY.
WE ARE GOING TO GET THE
TINKERING.
PERHAPS MAYBE MORE PERMANENCY.
THE STOCK MARKET WILL BE HAPPY
FOR SIX MONTHS.
THE MID-TERMS BECOMES HARDER.
BOEHNER DID A GOOD JOB.
THEY THINK HE SCREWED UP BUT
I'D LIKE THEM TO NAVIGATE THE
WATER.
>> Andrea: COME TO THE
TABLE -- I HAVE GIVE YOU
CREDIT.
YOU HAVE COME TO THE TABLE
WITH REAL OFFERINGS UP.
THE DEMOCRATS DON'T HAVE THE
POLITICAL APPETITE TO TOUCH
THE ENTITLEMENT.
THE PRESIDENT CONCEDEED
NOTHING?
>> UP TO $400,000.
>> Bob: CAN HE SELL THE
ENTITLEMENT CUTS TO THE KU
CUSS?
HE COULDN'T.
THE BOEHNER HAD $600,000 AND
ENTITLEMENT REFORM, YES, HE
COULD.
>> THIS DOES NOT GET US A
DEFICIT REDUCTION.
IF THIS IS HOW THEY WANT TO
PLAY THE GAME, BY MISSING A
HUGE OPPORTUNITY, ALL RIGHT.
YOU KNOW WHO LOSES?
>> Andrea: WE DO.
>> YES.
>> A MARINE WHO SERVED IN IRAQ
AND AFGHANISTAN IS LANGUISHING
IN ONE OF THE MOST DANGEROUS
PRISONS IN MEXICO ON TRUMPED
UP CHARGES.
SO WHY ISN'T THE
U.S. GOVERNMENT STEPPING IN
ERIC HAS THAT STORY UP NEXT.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] CAMPBELL'S
GREEN BEAN CASSEROLE.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
BY SHOWING YOU
THE APARTMENT BUILDING
WHERE THE FIRE WAS.
WHEN THINGS LIKE THIS HAPPEN,
I THINK YOU FIND
A NEW PERSPECTIVE ON LIFE.
RED CROSS PUT US IN A HOTEL
SO WE WERE ABLE
TO STAY TOGETHER.
WE'RE STRONG
AND IF WE OVERCAME THAT
OR IF WE CAN OVERCOME THAT...
WE CAN OVERCOME ANYTHING.
[ SNIFFLES ]
♪
>> Eric: WELCOME BACK.
NOW TO A STORY WE HAD BEEN ALL
OVER HAD WE NOT BEEN BUSY
COVERING THE TRAGIC
CONNECTICUT MASSACRE.
MARINE HAMMER HELD BEHIND BARS
IN A MEXICAN JAIL FOR FOUR
MONTHS.
HE AND A BUDDY WERE HEADED TO
MEXICO TO HUNT AND FISH.
THEY BROUGHT A GUN WITH HIM IN
A R.V.
AND HAMMER WAS TOLD BY THE
AGENT TO DECLARE THE RIFLE TO
MEXICAN AGENTS, WHICH HE DID.
AT THAT TIME, HAMMER WAS
ARRESTED.
THAT WAS AUGUST.
THIS IS A U.S. MARINE, CHANGE
TO A BED IN A MEXICAN PRISON.
DISGUSTING.
NOW LISTEN TO HIS PARENTS.
>> THIS IS WRONG.
DO THEHT THING.
HE SHOULD BE RELEASED MEALY.
SHE NOT A GUN RUNNER.
YOU KNOW IT.
>> Eric: WHERE IS ERIC
HOLDER?
HE HAD ZERO PROBLEMS TO GET
GUNS TO DRUG LORDS.
MADAM SECRETARY, AND
MR. HOLDER, FREE THIS MARINE
NOW.
THE LEAST YOU CAN DO.
WHERE ARE HILLARY AND HOLDER?
>> Bob: THE SUGGESTION THAT
THEY ARE IN A POSITION TO FREE
THEM.
THE MEXICANS HAVE TO MAKE THAT
DECISION.
KEEP IN MIND, WE PUT ALL KIND
OF PRESSURE ON THE MEXICANS
ABOUT THEIR DRUG RUNNING.
PART OF THIS IS A PAY BACK FOR
MEXICANS.
ARE THEY HOLDING OUT TO GET A
GET BACK FOR WHAT WE HAVE BEEN
DOING TO THEM WITH PUTTING THE
HEAT ON THEM ABOUT GUN RUNNIN
RUNNING?
A PART.
NOT RIGHT BUT NOT AN ISSUE OF
THE UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT.
>> Eric: CAN I ASK YOU WE
HAVE BEEN PUTTING ON THEM
ABOUT THE GUN RUNNING?
>> WE MADE A POINT FOR GOOD
REASON.
I'M NOT SUGGESTING IT'S NOT.
>> THEY HAVE BEEN AT THE GUN
RUNNING.
SOME SAY ENOUGH IS ENOUGH
>> Andrea: THE
ADMINISTRATION BARELY --
>> Eric: RIGHT NOW, RIGHT
NOW, WITH THE PEN RELEASE AND
WHY DOESN'T HE?
BOST GOT ME.
>> Bob: THIS ADMINISTRATION
HASN'T BEEN TALKING ABOUT GUN
RUNNING.
THAT IS THE PROBLEM.
>> Andrea: TODAY, CARNEY WAS
ASKED ABOUT THEM.
PLAYED DUMB OR MAYBE HE DIDN'T
KNOW.
THE STATE DEPARTMENT KNOWS
ABOUT IT.
CONGRESSWOMAN APPEALING TO
SECRETARY CLINTON TO DO
SOMETHING ABOUT THIS.
IS THIS THE STATE DEPARTMENT
NOT TALKING?
CAN YOU GET TOGETHER AND
CONNECT BEFORE ANOTHER
AMERICAN GETS KILLED?
>> IS IT POSSIBLE JAY CARNEY
DOESN'T KNOW WHO HAMMER IS?
OR HE IS HELD IN MEXICAN
PRISON?
>> I SUPPOSE SO.
HE SAID HE DIDN'T KNOW
ANYTHING ABOUT THE CASE.
THAT IS POSSIBLECH ONE RULE
THAT I HAD IS I BETTER NEVER
GET SURPRISED AT THE PODIUM BY
SOMETHING THAT MIGHT COME UP.
IF I DID, IS THERE WAS
H-E-DOUBLE HOCKEY STICKS TO
PAY.
>> Greg: DID YOU DO THAT?
>> Dana: I CAN'T SAY THE
WORD ON TV.
MEXICAN AND UNITED STATES
GOVERNMENT HAS TO RESPECT EACH
OTHER'S LAWS.
THEY SHOULD HAVE BEEN ABLE TO
WORK THIS OUT.
GUN RUNNING, FAST AND FURIOUS
IS GUNS GOING THAT WAY, NOT
OUR WAY.
>> ONLY ERIC HOLDER BRING IT
IN.
>> Greg: I WAS GOING TO SAY
THE STATE DEPARTMENT IS
NOWHERE TO BE FOUND ON
BENGHAZI.
NOWHERE TO BE FOUND ON THIS.
THEY DUCK MORE HITS THAN A
WHACKABALL AT THE FAIR.
WHAT DRIVES ME NUTS IF YOU
LOOK AT OTHER COUNTRIES, THE
PRISONS LOOK BAD.
I WISH OTHER COUNTRYS FEARED
OUR PRISONS LIKE THAT.
>> Andrea: LIKE GITMO?
>> Greg: WHY CAN'T OUR
PRISONS WERE LESS SCARY THAN
THEIR -- WHY CAN'T YOUR
PRISONS BE SCARIER THAN THEIR
PRISONS?
>> Bob: THERE ARE HUNDREDS
OF AMERICANS IN JAIL IN
MEXICO.
THIS HAS GOT A HIGH PROFILE.
DON'T THINK THEY WANT TO
PUNISH HIM.
>> Eric: OUR PRESIDENT
SIGNED WITH HIS EXECUTIVE
ORDER TO PROVIDE SOME FORM OF
AMNESTY.
$12 MILLION OR SO.
THEY CAN SEND THE MARINE BACK.
>> Bob: HAVE THE
CONVERSATION WITH THE
PRESIDENT OF MEXICO.
>> Andrea: ARE YOU SAYING WE
DON'T HAVE LEVERAGE?
THE FIRST WAS WITH FOX?
>> Bob: WE HAVE SOME
LEVERAGE.
>> I HOPE SO.
>> Bob: THIS GOVERNMENT DOES
NOT CARE WITH WHAT IS GOING ON
WITH THIS GUY IS DEAD WRONG.
WHY IS IT HELD LIKE THAT?
MY GUESS IS A LITTLE BIT OF
THE MEXICANS DOING PAYBACK.
>> Eric: WE HAVE TO GO.
COMING UP, N.F.L. PLAYER
CHARGED WITH THE TEXAS CODE
4908, INTOXICATION
MANSLAUGHTER AFTER A CRASH
KILLED HIS BEST FRIEND WAS
BACK ON THE FIELD THIS
WEEKEND.
SHOULD THE N.F.L. AND DALLAS
BOISE LET THIS HAPPEN?
THE DEBATE COMING UP.
♪
OKAY, HERE'S THE PLAN.
YOU HAVE A PLAN?
FIRST WE'RE GONNA
CHECK OUR BAGS FOR FREE,
THANKS
TO OUR EXPLORER CARD.
THEN, THE UNITED CLUB.
MY MOTR
WAS SO WRONG ABOUT YOU.
NEXT,
WE GET PRIORY BOARDING
ON OUR FLIGHT
I BOOKED WITH MILES.
ALL BECAUSE OF THE CARD.
AND ME.
OKAY, WHAT'S THE PLAN?
PLAN?
MM-HMM.
WE'RE ON VACATION.
THERE IS NO PLAN.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ] THE UNITED
MILEAGEPLUS EXPLORER CARD.
THE MILEAGE CARD
WITH SPECI PERKS ON UNITED.
GET IT AND YOU'RE IN.
but with ADVAIR,
I'm breathing better.
So now I can be in
the scene.
ADVAIR is
clinically proven to help
significantly improve
lung function.
Unlike most COPD medications,
ADVAIR contains both an
anti-inflammatory
and a
long-acting bronchodilator
working together to help improve
your lung function all day.
ADVAIR won't
replace fast-acting inhalers
for sudden symptoms
and should not be used more
than twice a day.
People with
COPD taking ADVAIR
may have a higher chance
of pneumonia.
ADVAIR may increase your
risk of osteoporosis
and some eye problems.
Tell your doctor
if you have a heart condition
or high blood pressure before
taking ADVAIR.
If you're still
having difficulty breathing,
ask your doctor if including
ADVAIR could help
improve your lung function.
Get your
first full
prescription
free
and save
on refills
at
ADVAIRcopd.com.
>>> I'M BRET BAIER IN
WASHINGTON.
THE BIG STORY HERE, DEAL
MAKING ON THE FISCAL CLIFF.
IS THERE A BREAK-THROUGH?
TONIGHT ON "SPECIAL REPORT,"
DESPITE CONCESSIONS ON BOTH
SIDES OF THE AISLE, PRESIDENT
OBAMA AND BOEHNER ARE PLAYING
POLITICAL HARDBALL.
THE WHITE HOUSE INSISTS THEY
ARE MAKING A GOOD FAITH EFFORT
TO REACH A COMPROMISE AS
BOEHNER IS READYING WHAT HE
CALLS PLAN B.
WE WILL LAY IT OUT FOR YOU.
STUDENTS IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, REELING FROM THE
DEADLY SCHOOL SHOOTING WERE
BACK IN THE CLASSROOM TODAY.
DIFFERENT CLASSROOMS.
THE MASSACRE SPARKED INTENSE
DEBATE IN WASHINGTON OVER GUN
CONTROL LEGISLATION AND WHAT
CAN BE DONE TO CUSH VIOLENCE
ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
THE NRA IS NOW WEIGHING IN.
THE NATIONAL DEBT, HOW MUCH DO
YOU OWE?
WE'LL BREAK DOWN NUMBERS TO
TAKE A FRIGHTENING LOOK AT
THAT IN PART WITH THE OF THE
SERIES, "THE COST OF SPENDIN
SPENDING."
NOW BACK TO NEW YORK AND MY
COLLEAGUES WITH "THE FIVE."
>> Dana: WELCOME BACK.
AFTER BEING CHARGED WITH
INTOXICATING MANSLAUGHTER OF
HIS TEAMMATE, HE CHEERED ON
THE TEAM FROM THE SIDELINES.
AFTER MOUNTING PRESSURE THE
COWBOYS ANNOUNCED TODAY THEY
WON'T ALLOW HIM ON THE
SIDELINE IN THE GAME.
THIS STORY CAUGHT MY EYE.
ON A FLIGHT ON THE WAY BACK,
TELEVISIONS WATCHING THE GAME.
>> Greg: MUST BE NICE.
>> Dana: NOT THAT NICE.
THE COMMENTATORS SAYING WHO IS
THAT?
WHAT IS HE DES MOINES THERE
WAS JOSH BRENT IN HIS
SWEATPANT PATTING THE
TEAMMATES ON THE BACK.
WAS THAT BIZARRE?
>> Eric: I'M NOT SURE THE
MANAGEMENT KNEW HE WAS DOING
THAT.
I GUESS THAT THEY WOULD ABOUT
WANT HIM TO DO THAT.
I WOULDN'T WANT HIM THERE.
YOU WAIT UNTIL HE IS CONVICTED
OF THINGS BUT IN THE MEANTIME,
LOOK HOW HE IS DRESSED.
>> Dana: I WAS SURPRISED HE
WOULD HAVE SHOWN UP ANYWAY.
PERSONALLY, I WOULD HAVEN'T
DONE THAT.
COULD YOU PUT ON SUIT OR DRESS
UP OR SOMETHING?
>> Greg: THE LEAST OF THE
PROBLEM IS WHAT HE IS WEARING.
I LOVE ALCOHOL AND CARS BUT
DON'T MIX THEM.
NO JOKES THERE.
$400 PEOPLE ON THE SIDELINE.
THERE ARE MORE PEOPLE EVERY
GAME.
THEY DID NOT NOTICE HE WAS
THERE.
>> Dana: THE DECEASED'S
MOTHER SAID SHE ACTUALLY
BACKED BRENT AND SAID SHE
WANTED A TEAMMATE TO SHOW
KINDNESS.
RECOGNIZED IT WAS AN ACCIDENT.
A BAD DECISION THAT DOESN'T
SHOW THERE ARE CONSEQUENCES
FOR YOUR ACTION.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
I DON'T THINK THE INTENTIONS
WERE BAD.
BUT THE COWBOYS SHOULD KNOW
ABOUT THE CONTROVERSY PEOPLE
ON THE SIDELINE TO GIVE THEM
BAD HEADLINES.
REMEMBER WHEN JESSICA SIMPSON
DATED TONY ROMO?
THEY HAVE BEEN THROUGH THIS
BEFORE.
BUT I AGREE YOU HAVE YOUNG
KIDS IN THE AUDIENCE WITH
FAMILY WATCHING THE GAME.
THEY KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
IT MAKES IT SEEM YOU CAN DO
THIS AND BE ON THE SIDELINE.
THEY SAID THEY ARE NOT GOING
TO LET HIM ON THE SIDELINE
ANYMORE.
IT'S VERY SMART.
I DON'T THINK THEY DID IT
MALICIOUSLY, THOUGH.
I UNDERSTAND THEY WANT TO
SUPPORT HIM.
BUT IF IT HAPPENED ON OUR TEAM
IT WOULD BE WEIRD.
WOULD HAVE COULD YOU NOT
NOTICE HE WAS THERE?
>> Bob: HOW DO YOU NOT
NOTICE?
HE HAS BEEN IN PAPER AND THE
PRESS.
WE KNOW WHO HE IS.
IT WAS A TERRIBLE DECISION TO
HAVE HIM THERE.
THIS GUY IS RESPONSIBLE FOR
DEATH OF ONE OF THE TEAMMATES.
MAY HAVE BEEN HIS BEST FRIEND
BUT HE DRANK, GOT DRUNK,
FLIPPED A CAR OVER AND
TEAMMATE WAS KILLED.
HE NEEDS REHABILITATION UP AND
GO TO JAIL.
HE SHOULD NOT GOING TO
SIDELINE OF THE DALLAS COWBOYS
GAME THAT SHOWS ME THE COWBOYS
ARE -- THEY'RE MISMANAGED.
OWNED BY A MISMANAGED OWNER.
DYNE YOU THINK IT HURTS THE
COWBOYS OR WATER UNDER THE
BRIDGE?
>> Eric: THIS IS LESS ABOUT
WHAT THE PLAYERS ARE THINKING
BUT EVERY KID WATCHING THAT
GAME.
TOOK A CAR AND KILLED HIS BEST
FRIEND BUT HE IS ON THE
SIDELINE.
COULDN'T BE THAT BAD.
CAN WE POINT OUT THAT THE
DALLAS COWBOYS AND ONE REPORT
SAYS THEY DIDN'T KNOW HE WAS
GOING TO BE THERE.
BEFORE YOU START INDICTING
JERRY JONES AND THE MANAGEMENT
TEAM, BOB, MAKE SURE THEY WERE
AWARE OF THAT.
>> Bob: HOW DO THEY NOT KNOW
IN THE BONE OWNER'S BOX D.
>> Greg: HE HAS A PASS.
>> Bob: LIFT THE PASS.
>> Dana: OUT ON BAIL.
HE GOT AN ANKLE BRACELET.
BOND CONDITION HE IS NOT
ALLOWED TO CONSUME ALCOHOL OR
DRIVE.
>> Andrea: HE MADE A BAD
DECISION WITH THE FIRST PLACE.
NOW HE IS MAKING BAD DECISIO
DECISIONS.
>> Dana: MAYBE HE NEEDS
HELP.
COMING UP, IS YOUR CHRISTMAS
DINNER GOING INCLUDE BIG MACS,
CHICKEN McNUGGETS AND FRYS?
THAT IS WHAT McDONALD'S IS
HOPING FOR.
BOB WILL EXPLAIN THAT AHEAD.
♪
>> Bob: BY THE WAY, THAT IS
ONE OF GREG'S FAVORITE SONGS.
"CAROL ON THE BELLS."
WE WANT CHRISTMAS SPIRIT ON
THE SHOW AND HOPE TO USE THAT
NOW.
SPEAKING OF, WHICH
McDONALD'S WANT ALL THE
RESTAURANTS OPEN ON CHRISTMAS
DAY THIS YEAR.
THAT'S RIGHT.
AFTER OPENING THANKSGIVING DAY
AND GETTING A BIG BOOST OF
REVENUE, HOPE AFTER ALL THE
PRESENTS AND EGGNOG THAT YOUR
FAMILY WILL GET A CRAVING FOR
BIG MAC.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
YOU THINK IS ENTERPRISE, HAVE
ALL THE BIG MACS YOU WANT ON
CHRISTMAS DAY, EASTER, DOESN'T
MATTER, RIGHTS?
>> IF YOU DON'T WANT TO WORK,
THEY DON'T TO WORK.
FREE MARKET.
FREE ENTERPRISE.
>> Bob: HOW DO YOU KNOW THEY
DON'T HAVE TO WORK?
>> Eric: THEY WON'T WORK.
CHRISTMAS.
>> Bob: BUT THEY SENT OUT A
MEMO SAYING WE WANT YOU TO
WORK BECAUSE YOU HAD A GOOD
THANKSGIVING.
>> Eric: IF IT DOESN'T WORK
OUT AND NO ONE SHOWS UP AND
LINE DOWN THE BLOCK, THEY
WON'T DO THAT.
OR PAY PEOPLE MORE.
LET THE FREE MARKET ESTABLISH
THE PRICE AND THE VALUE.
>> Bob: WHAT IF SOMEBODY
DOESN'T WANT TO GO TO WORK --
>> Andrea: DON'T GO.
>> Eric: TELL McDONALD'S
THEY CAN'T OPEN?
>> Bob: IF AN EMPLOYEE
DECIDES HE DOESN'T WANT TO
WORK ON CHRISTMAS AND STORE IS
OPEN --
>> Andrea: THEY GET FIRED.
THAT IS THE MANAGER'S
POSITION.
>> Bob: HO, HO, HO.
>> Andrea: I THINK IT'S
GENIUS.
BOSTON YOU DO?
>> Andrea: RESTAURANTS ARE
THE BUSIEST ON BREAKFAST.
DO YOU KNOW HOW MANY PEOPLE
WILL WAKE UP CHRISTMAS DAY,
TIRED OF BEING WITH THE HOUSE
AND KIDS HAVE BEEN OPENING
KIDS ALL DAY.
THEY GO TO DINERS AND
RESTAURANTS AND McDONALD'S.
GET BREAKFAST.
MAYBE SOME PEOPLE EAT THEIR
BIG MEAL AT 1:00 AND THEY'RE
HUNGRY AT 8:00 P.M.
>> Bob: YOU ARE SAYING THIS
BECAUSE YOU WORKED CHRISTMAS
DAY.
>> Andrea: IT WAS THE ONLY
DAY WE WERE CLOSED.
24 HOURS A DAY, 364 DAYS.
THE ONLY DAY.
>> Bob: DANA, WHAT DO YOU
THINK?
TOO MUCH?
>> Dana: NO.
PEOPLE WANT TO EAT
McDONALD'S, THAT IS GREAT.
IN THE OPENING YOU SAID
REVENUE AS IF IT WAS A BAD
WORD.
I THINK IT WAS -- I DON'T WANT
TO BE HYPOCRITICAL.
I THOUGHT IT WASN'T NECESSARY
FOR SHOPS TO BE OPEN ON
THANKSGIVING.
BUT I GUESS THAT WORKED OUT
OKAY FOR PEOPLE IF THEY WANT
TO SHOP, THEY COULD.
IF YOU WANT TO EAT
McDONALD'S YOU CAN.
I DON'T HAVE ANY FOOD IN THE
HOUSE.
MIGHT WORK OUT WELL FOR ME.
>> Bob: WHAT DO YOU THINK?
EAT ATED?
>> Greg: ABSOLUTELY.
THE JOBS ARE IMPORTANT TO
PEOPLE.
NOT EVERYBODY CAN BE OBAMA'S
JULIA AND NOT WORK.
BY THE WAY, THIS WOULD BE A
GREAT PROMOTIONAL THING TO
BRING BACK IN THE HOLIDAYS,
McRIB.
THEY SHOULD CALL IT THE
McREINDEER AND HAVE A
REINDEER WITH THE SIDE EXPOSED
FOR THE REINDEER RIBS.
>> Dana: GROSS.
>> Greg: RAPID McDONALD IS
A SANTA WITH A DEEP FRYER AND
BIG LIPS.
BEAUTIFUL.
>> Bob: IT'S OKAY IF SOMEONE
DOESN'T WANT TO SHOW UP, WANT
TO OPEN PRESENTS WITH THEIR
KIDS AND THEY DON'T WANT TO
WORK SO THEY GET FIRED?
>> Bob: THERE IS PROBABLY
ENOUGH PEOPLE TO GET.
>> Dana: PEOPLE IN
TELEVISION WORK CHRISTMAS DAY.
>> Dana: WE'RE WORKING.
>> Bob: I'M WORKING ON NEW
YEAR'NEWYEAR'S EVE AND CHRISTMA.
>> Bob: MINIMUM WAGE, TOO.
>> Andrea: IF THEY DON'T
WANT TO SHOW UP, THERE WILL BE
SOMEBODY ELSE ON THE SCHEDULE
TO TAKE THE MONEY.
WANT TO COME.
IN
>> Dana: MIGHT WANT THE
SHIFT.
>> Andrea: I DON'T THINK MY
DAD COULD GET ANYONE BUT HIS
OWN CHILDREN THERE.
WASN'T ENOUGH OF US.
>> Eric: VAST MAJORITY OF
THE McDONALD'S RESTAURANTS
ARE FRANCHISESE SO THEY PAY
MORE.
McDONALD'S CAN SAY WE
SUGGEST YOU OPEN BUT THEY
CAN'T SAY, MANDATE THEY OPEN.
>> Bob: DO YOU KNOW
McDONALD'S TESTED OUT
RESTAURANTS AND SOME OF THEM,
THE DRIVE-THROUGHS YOU MAKE
THE ORDER AND 7% MISTAKES.
NOW THEY OUTSOURCED IT TO
INDIA.
AND WHEN YOU PUT THE ORDER IN,
IT GOES TO INDIA AND COMES
BACK TO THE PEOPLE.
>> Greg: IN INDIA YOU CAN'T
EAT COWS.
CORRECT?
>> Bob: CORRECT.
UNBELIEVABLE.
THE MISTAKES IN ORDERS FELL.
>> Eric: ARE YOU TRYING TOLL
ME WHEN I PULL UP TO A
McDONALD'S, TALK IN A
SPEAKER IT GOES TO INDIA?
>> Bob: MAKE A BET.
>> Eric: I CALL B.S. ON
THIS.
I'LL MAKE A BET.
>> Bob: I'LL BET YOU $1,000.
>> Eric: ALL McDONALD'S?
>> Bob: I SAID 15
McDONALD'S WERE TRYING IT
OUT.
>> Eric: I'M NOT PAYING
THAT.
SURE.
>> Dana: YOU ALREADY SHOOK.
>> Eric: TRY AGAIN.
HE CHANGED IT.
>> Bob: I DIDN'T CHANGE THE
BET.
>> Eric: THEY MOVE IT --
>> Bob: I SAID SOME
RESTAURANTS ARE TRYING THIS
OUT.
>> Greg: YOU KNOW WHAT IS
GREAT FOR STOCKING STUFFERS,
McENACTS OR BIG MACS.
>> Dana: THE WOOL ON THE
STOCKING --
>> Greg: IT'S ROUGHAGE.
FIBER.
>> Bob: HAVE YOU EVER HAD
McDONALD'S IN A CAR?
>> Dana: NOTHING LIKE WHEN
YOU COME HOME --
>> Greg: I LOVE IT.
PERFUME FOR SAD PEOPLE LIKE
ME.
>> Bob: EXACTLY.
ONE MORE THING IS UP NEXT.
♪
>> Greg: TIME NOW FOR ONE
MORE THING.
ANDREA, KICK IT OFF.
>> Andrea: LAST WEEK, IF YOU
MISSED IT THURSDAY EVENING,
"THE FIVE" FEATURED ON
ENTERTAINMENT MAGAZINE PROGRAM
"ENTERTAINMENT TONIGHT."
>> THE 5:00 HOUR ON FOX NEWS
CHANNEL, FIVE ANCHORS, FIVE
OPINIONS.
>> IT MADE SENSE WHEN IT COMES
TO THE HANDING OUT FREEBIES
THINGS.
>> WEEKDAYS, GREG GUTFELD,
ANDREA TANTAROS, ERIC BOLLING,
DANA PERINO, KIMBERLY
GUILFOYLE, AND BOB BECKEL ARE
AMONGST THE HOSTS TO TRADE
BARBS ON THE TOPIC OF THE DAY.
>> WENT OUT WITH EMOTION HERE.
>> DANA.
>> BOB IS OFTEN THE
INSTIGATOR.
>> WHEN WERE YOU MARRIED?
ONE OF THE THREE MARRIAGES.
>> GREG PROVIDES COMIC RELIEF.
>> I WANT MORE BIEBER AND MORE
ROYALTY.
>> ELECTRIC MIX.
>> FANTASTIC.
>> UNSCRIPTED.
>> MOST INNOVATIVE SHOW ON
TELEVISION.
>> Andrea: BOB CAN'T FOLLOW
DIRECTIONS.
ONE WORD, ROBERT.
>> Bob: WASN'T THAT ONE
SNORE
>> MORE THAN THAT.
THANK YOU FOR FEATURING US.
WE APPRECIATE IT.
>> Greg: SAY SOMETHING
NON-JASPER RELATED.
>> Dana: I'LL TALK ABOUT
GEORGE W. BUSH THEN.
HE HAS BEEN -- GEORGE H.W.
BUSH IS TREATED FOR
COMPLICATION FROM BRONCHITIS
AND IN A HOSPITAL IN HOUSTON.
DOING BETTER AND BY ALL
ACCOUNT HE IS SHOULD BE HOME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
ONE THING HE LOVES IS TEXAS
AMES FOOTBALL.
WHERE HIS LIBRARY IS.
AND JOHNNY MANZIEL -- ERIC IS
TELLING ME TO CALL HIM "JOHNNY
FOOTBALL" SO I'M NOT SURE IF
HIS NAME IS JOHNNY FOOTBALL.
PRESIDENT BUSH GOT A SIGNED
FOOTBALL FROM HIM.
AND DID HEISEMAN.
>> Eric: WOULD I LEAD YOU
WRONG?
TAKE A LOOK AT MY FAVORITE
GOVERNOR CHRIS CHRISTIE.
MY FAVORITE GOVERNOR.
HE GOT ENDORSEMENT OF LABORS
INTERNATIONAL UNION OF NORTH
AMERICA.
DANA POINTED SOMETHING
IMPORTANT OUT.
THE "WALL STREET JOURNAL" RAN
A STORY, COREY BOOKER THOUGHT
TO BE HIS BIGGEST CHALLENGER
FOR GOVERNOR OF NEW JERSEY MAY
LOOK AT THE NEW JERSEY SENATE
SEAT WHICH WOULD CREATE
GOVERNOR CHRISTIE TO BE
GOVERNOR OF NEW JERSEY.
>> Greg: I WAS ON A BOOK
TOUR THIS WEEKEND GOING
THROUGH TEXAS, LOUISIANA,
OKLAHOMA.
BOB, POOH.
IST AT BARNS AND NOBLE --
>> Bob: WHAT IS THE NAME OF
THE BOOK?
>> Greg: "JOY OF HATE."
THE FIRST GROUP, FAMILY,
WAITING IN LINE.
LOOK WHAT THEY ARE WEARING?
THE SHIRTS THERE SAY "WHO
BUSHEPUSHED THE VIDEO?"
>> Dana: THEY DID IT IN
GREEN SO YOU STAND OUT AND PAY
ATTENTION TO THEN.
>> Greg: LOOK HOW GOOD IN
SHAPE I LOOK THERE.
BUT ANYWAY, THEY GIVE ME
SHIRTS ONE MORE BOBBISM DON'T
THINK --
>> Dana: WERE YOU OUT ON
BAIL?
>> Greg: NO GONDOLIER GUY.
>> Bob: GONDOLIER IN
>> Greg: I DON'T KNOW WHAT
I'M SAYING.
I'M TIRED.
>> Bob: THAT IS BECAUSE YOU
HAVE BEEN SELLING THE BOOK SO
MUCH.
TIRE THING.
MIFF ONE MORE THING IS A GUY
NAMED TIMOTHY THOMPSON GETS