AS WE ALL SO FERVENTLY DO.
BILL: YOU THINK ABOUT THE
TEACHERS AND EVERYONE ELSE.
REALLY THIS IS A DAY, THE
INVESTIGATION IS GOING TO GO
FORWARD.
IN ONE HOUR AS YOU MENTIONED,
MARTHA WE'LL HEAR FROM
LIEUTENANT ADVANCE YE VA NCE
YET AGAIN AND SEE WHAT
INFORMATION THEY ARE
UNCOVERING.
FOR TODAY THE FOCUS NEEDS TO BE
ON THE VICTIMS AND THEIR
FAMILIES AND RIGHTFULLY SO WHEN
WE SEE THE FIRST OF MANY
FUNERALS BEGIN HERE IN ABOUT TWO
HOURS.
WE WILL BE WATCHING THAT.
WE'LL HAVE COVERAGE THROUGHOUT
THE DAY HERE AND LET OUR VIEWERS
KNOW, IN THE MOST RESPECTFUL WAY
WE POSSIBLY CAN, WHAT IS
HAPPENING AND WHAT THEY NEED TO
KNOW ABOUT NEWTOWN.
WE'LL SEE YOU LATER, EVERYBODY.
"HAPPENING NOW" CONTINUES OUR
COVERAGE NOW.
JON: WE CONTINUE WITH BRAND-NEW
STORIES AND EVEN BREAKING NEWS.
JENNA: POLICE VOWING TO EXAMINE
EVERY SINGLE BULLET FOUND AT
SCENE AT THE MASSACRE AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
NO BETTER UNDERSTANDING OF WHAT
CAUSED THE KILLER TO COMMIT THIS
CRIME.
A LIVE UPDATE AN HOUR FROM NOW.
WE'LL TAKE YOU THERE.
A HORRIBLE SEEN IN KANSAS, TWO
POLICE OFFICERS SHOT, BOTH OF
THEM KILLED IN A DRAMATIC
STANDOFF WITH THE SUSPECT.
THE VERY LATEST ON THAT.
ALSO WE ARE SET TO GET DETAILS
FROM AN INDEPENDENT REPORT ON
THE TERRORIST ATTACK IN LIBYA,
FOUR AMERICANS MURDERED AT THE
U.S. CONSULATE THERE, SO MANY
QUESTIONS STILL ABOUT SECURITY
AND THE ADMINISTRATION'S
HANDLING OF THE AFTERMATH.
THOSE STORIES AND BREAKING NEWS
AS WE GET IT ALL "HAPPENING
NOW."
JON: AS WE BEGIN ON THIS MONDAY
THERE ARE NEW DEVELOPMENTS TO
TELL YOU ABOUT IN THE AFTERMATH
OF THE CONNECTICUT SCHOOL
MASSACRE.
GOOD MORNING I'M JON SCOTT.
JENNA: HI, EVERYBODY, I'M JENNA
LEAVE.
THE COUNTRY AS BILL AND MARTHA
WERE JUST TALKING ABOUT
STRUGGLING TO COME TO GRIPS WITH
THE DEADLIEST SHOOTING EVERY AT
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN THE
UNITED STATES, HOLDING VIGILS
AND MEMORIALS FOR THE 2* THE 26
LIVES CUT WAY TOO SHORT.
THE NUMBER DEAD IS 27.
A FUNERAL FOR TWO OF THE VICTIMS
OF THE MASSACRE, NOAH POSNER AND
JACK PINTO.
NOAH'S TWIN SISTER SURVIVED THE
ATTACK.
THE PRESIDENT SPOKE AT AN
INTEREST TERE FAITH SERVICE IN
NEWTOWN.
>> IT WAS SOMETHING YOU NEVER
REALLY SEE, ALL THE JOINT FAITHS
COMING TOGETHER AND SHARING AS
ONE.
I THOUGHT IT WAS REMARKABLE.
>> I DON'T EVEN LIVE IN THIS
TOWN, BUT I JUST WANTED TO GIVE
MY SUPPORT TO THE FAMILIES, AND
I HAVE LITTLE ONES OF MY OWN,
AND I WANTED -- I FEEL THEIR
GRIEF.
>> IN A TIME OF CRISIS LIKE THIS
WE ARE ONE, WE ARE ONE NATION.
JON: MEANTIME INVESTIGATORS ARE
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHAT
TRIGGERED ADAM LANZA'S DEADLY
RAMPAGE.
POLICE SAY THE 20-YEAR-OLD
KILLED HIS MOTHER AND TOOK OFF
WITH HER GUNS HEADING TO SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WITH
YOU'VE AMMO TO TAKEOUT ABOUT
EVERY STUDENT IN THERE.
>> HE SHOT HIS WAY INTO THE
SCHOOL.
THE SCHOOL WAS LOCKED.
HE USED A WEAPON TO OPEN UP THE
GLASS AND THEN --
>> HE BLASTED RIGHT THROUGH IT,
RIGHT?
>> WITH SEVERAL -- A NUMBER OF
ROUNDS.
HE DISCHARGED TO MAKE AN OPENING
AND THEN WENT THROUGH IT, WENT
TO THE FIRST CLASSROOM, AS YOU
KNOW, WENT TO THE SECOND
CLASSROOM.
WE SURMISE THAT IT WAS DURING
THE SECOND CLASSROOM EPISODE
THAT HE HEARD RESPONDERS COMING
AND APPARENTLY AT THAT DECIDED
TO TAKE HIS OWN LIFE.
JON: WELL THREE DAYS AFTER THIS
CARNAGE BEGAN THE CLASSES ARE
CANCELED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THERE ARE NOW QUESTIONS ABOUT
WHETHER THE SCHOOL WILL EVER
REOPEN ITS DOORS TO THE
EDUCATION OF CHILDREN.
RICK LEVENTHAL LIVE IN
CONNECTICUT.
THERTHERE WAS A BRIEFING.
>> Reporter: POLICE TOLD US THEY
WERE TOLDING TWO CRIME SCENES
INDEFINITELY.
THAT INCLUDES THE HOME WHERE
NANCY LANZA LIVED WITH HER SON
ADAM, WHERE SHE DIED AFTER HE
SHOT HER MULTIPLE TIMES IN THE
HEAD.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
ALSO A CRIME SCENE AS
INVESTIGATORS POURED THROUGHOUT
AREA WHERE HE WENT ON HIS
MURDERER RUST RAMPAGE KILLING
SIX ADULTS AND 20 CHILDREN.
INVESTIGATORS ARE GOING THROUGH
COMPUTER RECORDS, PHONE RECORDS
AND OTHER ELECTRONICS SERB -FPG
FOR CLUES AND A POSSIBLE MOTIVE
AND THEY ARE INTERVIEWS EVERY
SINGLE WITNESS TO FRIDAY'S
SHOOTING AND THAT INCLUDES THE
CHILDREN WHO SURVIVED.
I ASKED THE POLICE SPOKESMAN,
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE ABOUT THAT
EARLIER.
>> I DON'T WANT TO GIVE THE
DETAILS, IT'S A VERY, VERY, VERY
TENDER, TENDER ISSUE.
I CAN TELL YOU THAT ANY
INTERVIEWS WITH ANY CHILDREN
WILL BE DONE WITH PROFESSIONALS,
WITH PARENTS AND WITH
INVESTIGATORS AS APPROPRIATE.
THE INVESTIGATORS WILL DETERMINE
HOW, WHEN, WHERE AND WHY WE'LL
DO THIS.
AGAIN UNDERSTANDING WE WILL
HANDLE THAT EXTREMELY
DELICATELY.
>> Reporter: OBVIOUSLY A VERY
DIFFICULT SITUATION AND MORE
EVIDENCE THAT PEOPLE ARE ON EDGE
HERE.
THERE'S BEEN ANOTHER SITUATION
IN THE RIDGEFIELD SCHOOL
DISTRICT ABOUT 30 MINUTES AWAY.
SCHOOLS THERE ON LOCKDOWN AFTER
A WOMAN REPORTED SEEING A MAN
WITH A RIFLE AT A NEARBY TRAIN
STATION.
NO WORD ON WHETHER THEY FOUND
THAT MAN, BUT OBVIOUSLY, JON,
POLICE TAKING EVERY PRECAUTION.
JON: AND THE GUNMAN AT SANDY
HOOK, SO MANY QUESTIONS ABOUT
THE MOTIVATION AND THE
BACKGROUND.
WHAT ARE WE LEARNING ABOUT HIM.
>>> WE'VE EVER LEARNED A LOT
MORE AS ADAM LANZA WHO HAS BEEN
DESCRIBED AS A NEAR GENIUS WHO
HAD DEVELOPMENTAL ISSUES.
HE IS BELIEVED TO HAVE BEEN
SUFFERING FROM ASBURGER'S
SYNDROME, A FORM OF AUTISM.
HE WENT TO SANDY HOOK FOR A
SHORT TIME AS A CHILD, WAS
WITHDRAWN AND HOME SCHOOLED.
HE WENT TO WESTERN CONNECTICUT
STATE UNIVERSITY WHEN HE WAS
JUST 16 YEARS OLD AND TOOK SOME
COLLEGE COURSES THERE.
HE DROPPED OUT OF A COUPLE, HE
FINANCE EURPB FINISHED A COUPLE
OF OTHERS, HIS GRADE POINT
AVERAGE WAS 3.26, HE NEVER
GRADUATED FROM THERE.
WE SAW DIVORCE PAPERS BETWEEN
HIS PARENTS.
THE MOTHER WAS AUTHORIZED TO
MAKE DECISIONS ON HIS UPBRINGING
AND WE HAVE LEARNED AS WELL THAT
THE MOTHER OWNED THE WEAPONS
THAT ADAM BROUGHT TO THE SCHOOL
INCLUDING THAT BUSHMASTER
223AR15.
IT'S A CIVILIAN VERSION OF THE
MILITARY M16 RIFLE DESCRIBED AS
THE MOST POPULAR RIFLE IN
AMERICA.
HE WAS ALSO CARRYING TWO
HANDGUNS AND USED ONE OF THEM TO
KILL HIMSELF AS POLICE CLOSED
IN.
JON, AS YOU MENTIONED CLASSES AT
SANDY HOOK, OF COURSE THE
NEWTOWN SCHOOL DISTRICT HAVE
BEEN CANCELED TODAY.
SANDY HOOK WILL BE CLOSED
INDEFINITELY.
THE STUDENTS WHO SURVIVED THE
SHOOTING WILL GO BACK TO SCHOOL
BUT SOMEWHERE ELSE.
WE ARE HEARING TODAY THAT SANDY
HOOK MAY NEVER REOPEN.
THEY ARE NOT SURE WHAT TO DO
WITH THAT FACILITY.
JON: SO MANY TOUGH DECISIONS
STILL TO BE MADE DOWN THE ROAD.
RICK LEVENTHAL IN NEWTOWN.
THANK YOU.
JENNA: WE KNOW SO MANY OF YOU IN
YOUR OWN COMMUNITIES ARE
DISCUSSING THIS TERRIBLE EVENT,
AND ACROSS THE COUNTRY IN
ARIZONA THOSE WHO SURVIVED THE
MASS SHOOTING AT GABRIELLE
GIFFORDS' IN TUCSON TWO
YEARS AGO CAME TOGETHER
YESTERDAY TO PRAY FOR THE
NEWTOWN VICTIMS.
CONGRESSMAN RON BARBER WHO
WORKED FORGIVE FORDS AND WAS
INJURED THAT DAY LED THE
CANDLELIGHT VIGIL.
HE WAS JOINED BY HIS YOUNG
GRANDCHILDREN ON STAGE.
THEY ARE THE SAME AGE AS THE
CHILDREN WHO LOST THEIR LIVES IN
CONNECTICUT.
CONGRESSWOMAN GIFFORDS WAS
HOLDING AN EVENT IN THAT SAFE
WAY PARKING LOT WHERE A LONE
GUNMAN SHOT HER, SPRAYED THE
PARKING LOT WITH BULLETS AND
KILLED SIX PEOPLE, INCLUDING A
LITTLE GIRL.
CONGRESSWOMAN GIFFORDS SURVIVED
AND CONTINUES TO MAKE PROGRESS.
THE KILLER WAS INITIALLY
DECLARED INCOMPETENT TO STAND
TRIAL.
IN AUGUST HE PLEADED GUILTY AND
WAS SENTENCED TO LIFE IN
PRISON.
JON: THE NATIONAL FOOTBALL
LEAGUE ALSO PAUSING TO REMEMBER
THE SCHOOL SHOOTING VICTIMS.
THE NEW YORK GIANTS PLAYED THEIR
GAME IN ATLANTA WITH HEAVY
HEARTS WEARING THE INITIALS SHES
FOR SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
ON THEIR HELL PHEPBTS.
GIANTS WIDE RECEIVER VICTOR
CRUISE WEARING THE NAME OF ONE
OF THE VICTIMS 6-YEAR-OLD JACK
PINTO ON HIS GLOVES AND SHOES.
CRUISE WAS JACK'S FAVORITE
PLAYER.
CRUISE SAID AFTER THE GAME HE
HOPES TO VISIT JACK'S FAMILY
SOME TIME THIS WEEK.
>> I SPOKE TO THE FAMILY.
I ALSO SPOKE TO THE OLDER
BROTHERS, AND HE WAS DISTRAUGHT
AS WELL.
I TOLD THEM TO STAY STRONG AND I
WILL DO WHATEVER I CAN.
JON: JACK PINTO ONE OF THE TWO
FUNERALS TO BE HELD TODAY.
MEANTIME IN NEW ENGLAND THE PIE
TREE ATS HONORING THE VICTIMS
WITH 26 WHITE FLARES SHOT INTO
THE SKY OVER THE STADIUM DURING
A MOMENT OF SILENCE.
THE TEAM ALSO PLEDGING $25,000
TO THE VICTIMS' FAMILIES.
JENNA: WITH A HEAVY HEART SO
MANY OF YOU PARENTS ARE SENDING
YOUR KIDS OFF TO SCHOOL TODAY.
FRIDAY'S VIOLENCE FORCING SO
MUCH US, INCLUDING PARENTS AND
ED INDICATORS TO CONFRONT WHAT
WE CAN DO IF ANYTHING TO MAKE
SCHOOLS SAFER AND MORE SECURE.
CHIEF WASHINGTON CORRESPONDENT
JAMES ROSEN IS TAKING A CLOSER
LOOK AT THIS FOR US TODAY.
>> Reporter: ACROSS THE COUNTRY
EDUCATORS AND ADD MINIMUM
STRAEURTS ARE STRIVIN
ADMINISTRATORS, ARE TRYING TO
TELL PARENTS THEIR SCHOOLS ARE
SAFE.
MEASURES BEING ADOPTED THIS
MORNING EXTEND ACROSS THE PUBLIC
AND PRIVATE SCHOOL CONTINUUM
WITH SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGISTS AND
COUNSELORS BRACING FOR QUESTIONS
AND GUIDANCE SESSIONS.
SECURITY OFFICERS ARE TALKING
WITH LOCAL POLICE AND PROCEDURES
FOR SAFETY DRILLS ARE BEING
REVISITED.
ONE CONCURRENT THEME IS THAT
TEACHES, PRINCIPALS AND OTHER
AUTHORITY FIGURES SEEM RELUCTANT
TO RAISE NEWTON WITH STUDENTS OF
THEIR OWN.
A MESSAGE WENT OUPBT IN FLORIDA
QUOTE, PLEASE KNOW THAT SCHOOL
STAFF MEMBERS WILL BE AVAILABLE
TO SPEAK TO INDIVIDUAL STUDENTS
SHOULD ANY OF THEM NEED ANYONE
TO TALK TO. WE WILL NOT BE
BRINGING UP THIS LATEST TRAGEDY
IN OUR CLASSROOMS OR
CONVERSATIONS, BUT WE WILL BE
THERE FOR OUR STUDENTS TO LISTEN
IF THEY HAVE CONCERNS ABOUT
SAFETY AT OUR SCHOOL, UNQUOTE.
HERE IS A SIMILAR MESSAGE THAT I
RECEIVED LAST NIGHT FROM MY
SON'S PRINCIPAL HERE IN THE
WASHINGTON D.C. AREA, QUOTE, OUR
APPROACH WILL BE TO ADDRESS IT
AS IT COMES UP ORGANICALLY WITH
STUDENTS.
SOME OF THE CHILDREN WILL HAVE
HEARD AND/OR SEEN DETAILS OF
THIS EVENT ON TV WHILE OTHERS
MAY HAVE BEEN SHIELDED FROM THE
MAJORITY OF THE INFORMATION.
I DO NOT WANT ADULT INITIATED
CONVERSATIONS TO IMPRESS MORE ON
THE CHILDREN THAN PARENTS
DESIRE.
UNDERLYING SUCH DECISIONS IS AN
AVERAGEment T ACKNOWLEDGMENT
TO THE OLDER KIDS.
THEY ARE LIKELY TO HAVE HEARD
ABOUT NEWTOWN ON THEIR OWN.
THEY SAY IF THEY ASK ABOUT THE
MASSACRE KEEP YOUR ANSWERS SHORT
AND SIMPLE AND IMPRESS UPON HEM
THAT THEY AND THEIR SCHOOLS ARE
SAFPLT.
JENNA ARE SAFE.
JON: IN CONNECTICUT POLICE ARE
POURING OVER EVERY PIECE OF
EVIDENCE THEY CAN FIND IN
NEWTOWN, INCLUDING THE GUNMAN'S
COMPUTER.
WHAT THEY HOPE TO FIND THAT
COULD SHED LIGHT ON A POSSIBLE
MOTIVE.
PLUS AN EXPLOSION TARGETING
AMERICAN PERSONNEL IN
AFGHANISTAN.
THE VERY LATEST ON WHAT HAPPENED
THERE.
THAT IS COMING UP .
JON: A POWERFUL CYCLONE RIPS
THRAOUP THE SOUTH PACIFIC
FLOODING PARTS OF FIJI TODAY
KILLING AT LEAST FOUR PEOPLE IN
THE SMALL STATE OF SAMOA.
UP TO A DOZEN PEOPLE THERE ARE
REPORTED MISSING.
AND THE PREGNANT DUTCHESS OF
CAMBRIDGE MAKING HER FIRST
PUBLIC APPEARANCE SINCE BEING
HOSPITALIZED FORAY CUTE MORNING
SICKNESS AND DEHYDRATION.
KATE MIDDLETON PRESENTING AWARDS
AT A UK SPORTS CEREMONY IN
LONDON.
JENNA: BACK TO OUR TOP STORY NOW
THE KOPBD CONNECTICUT SCHOOL
MASSACRE.
AS WE AWAIT THE FUNERALS OF TWO
YOUNG PEOPLE KILLED IN THAT
RAMPAGE INVESTIGATORS ARE
POURING OVERCOME PURSUITERS
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT HOW ADAM
LANZA PLANNED HIS SPREE.
WHERE DO YOU START THE
INVESTIGATION?
>> FIRST NEED TO PLEASE
ACKNOWLEDGE THE FAMILIES AND
SLIMS.
MY DEEPEST SYMPATHIES.
SO OUR DIGITAL LIVES ARE A
WINDOW INTO OUR MINDS.
AND BY DISCOVERING A PERSON'S
DIGITAL LIFE YOU ESSENTIALLY CAN
MAP OUT THEIR LIFE'S PAST AND
FUTURE INTENTIONS, AND THE POINT
OF A DIGITAL DISCOVERY
ESSENTIALLY IS TO FIND OUT WHAT
HAPPENED, AND ESSENTIALLY HOW TO
PREVENT THIS IN THE FUTURE AS
WELL.
JENNA: SO WHERE DO YOU START
WITH THE MATERIAL THAT YOU MIGHT
HAVE IN A TYPICAL CASE?
>> EASILY, VERY SIMPLY AS YOU
WOULD WITH YOUR OWN DEVICE, FROM
THE DESKTOP IN YOU SCAR THE HARD
DRIVE LOOKING THROUGH ALL
DIFFERENT DOCUMENT FOLDERS,
LOOKING AT ALL THE DIFFERENT
FILES AND FOLDERS, THE NAMES OF
THEM, THE DIFFERENT DOCUMENTS
WITHIN, AND THEN GOING THROUGH
WEB HISTORIES, WEB HISTORY CAN
DETERMINE WHAT WEB SITES THEY
VISITED.
ALSO BY LOOKING AT ANY FORENSICS
IN REGARDS TO CHAT LOGS, ANY
COMMUNICATIONS THAT THERE MIGHT
BE WITH OTHERS.
JENNA: HOW FAR BACK CAN YOU GO,
ROBERT WHEN YOU TALKED ABOUT
SOME OF THOSE HISTORIES THAT YOU
CAN LOOK THROUGH, FOR SOMEONE
THAT IS 20 20 YEARS OLD, FOR
EXAMPLE, WE UNDERSTAND THAT
THERE IS SOME EVIDENCE AT THE
MOTHER'S HOUSE BUT AUTHORITIES
HAVE BEEN VERY TIGHTLIPPED ABOUT
IT.
HOW FAR BACK WOULD ANY DEVICE, A
TYPICAL DEVICE IN A FAMILY'S
HOME PROVIDE YOU?
YEARS?
ARE WE TALKING MONTHS, WEEKS?
WHAT KIND OF TIMELINE.
>> GREAT QUESTION.
THINK OF YOUR OWN DIGITAL
DEVICES, FOR EXAMPLE WITHIN MY
OWN HOME AND OFFICE I HAVE
DEVICE AS OLD AS TEN TO 12 YEARS
OLD AND ALL OF THOSE HOLD
HISTORY OF WEB TRAFFIC, AND
EMAIL COMMUNICATIONS, AND YOU
CAN GO BACK AS LONG AS THE
DEVICE IS OLD.
AND IF THERE HAS BEEN ANY
TRANSFER OF DATA FROM AN EVEN
OLDER DEVICE THEN ALL THAT
HISTORY REMAINS.
JENNA: INTERESTING.
>> AND THEN IF THE PERSON WAS
PROFICIENT AT CLEARING THEIR
HISTORY, THEN THERE IS LESS
INFORMATION THAT CAN BE FOUND,
BUT, AGAIN, DEPENDING ON THE
OPERATING SYSTEM, IN DIFFERENT
PARTITIONS THAT MIGHT BE SET UP
A LOT OF DATA CAN BE DISCOVERED
WITH THE RIGHT TECHNOLOGY.
JENNA: THE AUTHORITIES AGAIN
HAVE BEEN VERY TIGHTLIPPED ABOUT
THE EVIDENCE THAT THEY HAVE.
WE HAVE INITIAL REPORTS, AND
AGAIN, WE DON'T KNOW IF THESE
REPORTS ARE REAL OR NOT, THAT
THE MURDERER MIGHT HAVE
DESTROYED SOME OF THE COMPUTER.
THE INITIAL REPORTS SAID A HARD
DRY.
AGAIN, WE DON'T KNOW IF THIS IS
TRUE.
IF THAT'S THE CASE, THE SCENARIO
YOU'RE DEALING WITH, DOES THAT
LIMIT YOU IN ANYWAY?
>> IT CERTAINLY DOES.
AND THE ABILITY OF THE OFFENDER
TO ESSENTIALLY DESTROY THAT
DEVICE VERSUS THE ABILITY OF SAY
A FORENSICS EXPERT TO DISCOVER
IT MAY VARY.
A GOOD FORENSICS EXPERT WITH THE
RIGHT TECHNOLOGY CAN GET DELET
DELETED OR EVEN DESTROYED DATA,
AGAIN, IT'S A COUNTY AND MOUS A
CAT AND MOUSE GAME.
BASED ON WHAT THEY ARE ALREADY
FINDING AND WHAT THEY WILL FIND
THEY'LL BE ABLE TO DETERMINE
WHETHER OR NOT THIS INDIVIDUAL
HAD CONSPIRED WITH OTHERS, AND
THEY WILL MORE THAN LIKELY FIND
WHAT HIS TRIGGER POINT MIGHT
HAVE BEEN IN ORDER TO BASICALLY
DEVICE THIS PLAN AND WHY.
JENNA: AT THE NEWS CONFERENCE ON
SATURDAY THE OFFICIALS SEEMED
HOPEFUL ABOUT THE EVIDENCE THAT
THEY FOUND AT THE MOTHER'S
HOUSE.
WE'LL WAIT TO SEE EXACTLY WHAT
THAT PRODUCES AND WHAT ANSWERS,
MAYBE, MAYBE IT PROVIDES IN A
CASE LIKE THIS.
ROBERT, GREAT TO SEE YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR EXPERTISE
TODAY.
>> THANK YOU.
JON: WE ARE GETTING BRAND-NEW
DETAILS ON THE DEADLY ATTACK ON
OUR CONSULATE IN LIBYA THAT
KILLED OUR AMBASSADOR AND THREE
OTHER MEN.
A NEW INDEPENDENT REPORT IS DUE
OUT.
WHAT IT COULD TELL US AS THE
STATE DEPARTMENT PREPARES TO
TESTIFY BEFORE CONGRESS ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED THERE.
PLUS, OUR COVERAGE CONTINUES ON
THE TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT.
COMING UP THE MASSACRE REOPEN
THE DEBATE ABOUT WHAT TO DO
ABOUT MENTAL ILLNESS IN THIS
COUNTRY.
JON: RIGHT NOW WE ARE AWAITING
DETAILS OF AN INDEPENDENT REPORT
ON THE DEADLY ASSAULT ON OUR
CONSULATE IN LIBYA.
THAT REPORT LOOKS INTO WHAT LED
UP TO THE ATTACK ON
SEPTEMBER 11th.
IT IS EXPECTED TO BE TURNED OVER
TO STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIALS
TODAY.
AS YOU KNOW FOUR AMERICANS WERE
KILLED IN OUR CONSULATE WHEN IT
CAME UNDER FIRE IN BENGHAZI,
INCLUDING OUR AMBASSADOR TO
LIBYA, CHRIS STEVENS.
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON CREATED THE INDEPENDENT
REVIEW BOARD, HOWEVER, SHE WILL
NOT BE ABLE TO TESTIFY AT THE
BENGHAZI HEARINGS LATER THIS
WEEK BECAUSE OF A CONCUSSION.
LET'S TALK ABOUT IT ALL WITH
STEVEN YATES A FORMER DEPUTY
ASSISTANT FOR THE VICE PRESIDENT
FOR NATIONAL SECURITY AFFAIRS
DURING THE BUSH ADMINISTRATION.
STEVEN, THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH
US TODAY.
>> GLAD TO BE WITH YOU, JON.
JON: THIS INDEPENDENT ADVISORY
REVIEW BOARD WAS APPOINTED BY
THE STATE DEPARTMENT.
DOES THAT MEAN IT'S CONTROLLED
BY THE STATE DEPARTMENT OR DOES
IT LIVE UP TO IT'S TITLE OF
INDEPENDENCE IN.
>> IT'S INDEPENDENT IN THE SENSE
THAT IT DOESN'T COME WITHIN THE
BUREAUCRACY.
IT WILL BE FORMER OFFICIALS THAT
GUIDE THE EFFORT.
IT WILL BE INFORMED VERY MUCH BY
SOURCES WITHIN THE BUREAUCRACY
ITSELF.
I THINK IT'S PART OF AN EFFORT
TO FOCUS MORE ON LOWER-LEVEL
BUREAUCRAT PARTICULAR DECISIONS
AND OPERATIONAL DECISIONS AND
AWAY FROM POLITICAL AND POLICY
DECISION HAS FED INTO THE
CONTROVERSY.
JON: DO YOU EXPECT WHATEVER IS
IN THE REPORT IS GOING TO END
THE CONTROVERSY OVER BENGHAZI?
I DOUBT VERY MUCH IT WILL END
THE CONTROVERTS SEE.
IT MAY ADVANCE THE
CONVERSATION.
THERE IS STILL A LOT OF
QUESTIONS ABOUT WHY THE SECURITY
POSTURE WAS WHERE IT WAS IN
BENGHAZI ON THAT FATEFUL DAY BUT
IT WON'T REALLY I THINK GET AT
THE BROADER QUESTION OF WHY DOES
THERE SEEM TO BE AN UNDER
ESTIMATION OF THE NATURE AND
SCOPE OF THE THREAT WE FACE IN
THAT BROADER REGION AND WHY DID
THE AMBASSADOR FEEL IT WAS
VISIBLADD VISIBLE TO TRAVEL
OUTSIDE OF THAT COMPOUND THAT
DAY.
JON: CONGRESS WILL BE TAKING A
LOCK AT THIS REPORT AS WELL,
CORRECT?
>> THEY WILL INDEED.
THAT WOULD HAVE BEEN THE SUBJECT
EVER HEARINGS FEATURING THE
SECRETARY OF STATE LATER IN THE
WEEK HAD IT NOT BEEN FOR HER
HEALTH ISSUES.
I PRESUME AT SOME POINT SHE WILL
STAND BEFORE THE COMMITTEES IN
THE HOUSE AND THE SENATE TO
OFFER HER ACCOUNT.
BUT EVEN THOSE WILL JUST BE
PIECES OF INFORMATION.
ULTIMATELY DECISIONS MADE IN THE
WHITE HOUSE AND THE EXECUTIVE
BRANCH IN THEIR INTERNAL
DELIBERATIONS TEND TO BE SHIELD
FROM CONGRESS.
ALL CONGRESS CAN DO IS CRY FOUL
AND CALL FOR MORE INFORMATION.
JON: EVERYONE IS WONDERING ABOUT
THE TIMING OF SECRETARY
CLINTON'S UNAVAILABILITY.
SHE WILL YOU EXPECT TESTIFY AT
SOME POINT ONCE SHE'SE SHE'S
RECOVERED FROM HER INJURY.
>> I THINK CONGRESS IS WITHIN
ITS RIGHTS TO CALL HER AT ANY
TIME.
I HAVE NO REASON TO SECOND-GUESS
HER HEALTH STANDING AT THE
CURRENT MOMENT.
I PRESUME THAT SHE WILL IMPROVE
IN HER HEALTH.
EVEN AFTER SHE IS NO LONGER
SECRETARY OF STATE SHE STILL
WOULD BE A KEY WITNESS WITH REAL
INFORMATION, TESTIFYING THE WAY
GENERAL PETRAEUS DID ALSO.
UT WHAT HAPPENED LOT OF
HERE THAT ARE GOING TO LIVE ON
BEYOND HER HOLDING OF THAT
OFFICE.
WOULD YOU EXPT THAT YOU'LL GET
SOME INFORMATION WHEN OTHER
INCOMING -- SAY IF IT IS SENATOR
KERRY WHO COMES IN AS SEC OF
STATE, WILL THERE BE MORE
INFORMATION FORTHCOMING?
>> WELL, I WOULD EXPECT THAT HE
WOULD HAVE EVERY INTEREST
INLETTING THIS BE YESTERDAY'S
BUSINESS AND TO MOVE ONTO
FOCUSING ON WHAT HE SEES AS THE
PRIORITY GUIDING HIS NEW TENURE
AS SEC OF STATE.
I DON'T THINK HE WOULD WANT TO
DRAW TOO MUCH ATTENTION TO IT.
BUT HE WOULD WANT TO AT LEAST
OPERATIONALLY WRAP-UP WHAT
HAPPENED WITH EMBASSY SECURITY
AND TPAOEP OTHER FACILITIE KEEP
OTHER FACILITIES GOING IN THE
FUTURE.
JON: WHOEVER SUCCEEDS HILLARY
CLINTON IS GOING TO FIND THE
SAME OPERATION IN PLACE, RIGHT?
THERE ARE THINGS THAT CLEARLY
NEED TO BE FIXED.
>> OPERATIONAL THINGS THAT NEED
TO BE FIXED.
THERE ARE THINGS IN CONJUNCTION
WITH THE MILITARY TO INSURE
THERE ARE RESCUE OPENINGS
READILY AVAILABLE SUDDEN CON SIN
GENT SEES PRESENT THEMSELVES.
THERE ARE POLICY DECISIONS, WHAT
IS THIS ENEMY, WHAT IS ITS
NATURE, HOW MUCH OF A THREAT
DOES IT POSE.
ARE WE TELLING THE TRUTH TO
OURSELVES ABOUT THE STATUS OF
TERRORISM AND ISLAMISM TODAY?
>> STEVEN, THANK YOU.
JENNA: BREAKING NEWS OUT OF
KANSAS WHERE AN ARMED STANDOFF
ACCUSED OF KILLING TWO POLICE
OFFICERS HAS JUST ENDED.
DRAMATIC DETAILS AHEAD.
PLUS WE REMEMBER THE HEROS IN
NEWTOWN, HOW THEIR ACTIONS SAVED
COUNTLESS LIVES.
>> Announcer: 'TIS THE SEASON
OF MORE--
MORE SHOPPING,
MORE DINING OUT...
AND ALONG WITH IT,
MORE IDENTITY THEFT.
BY THE TIME THIS HOLIDAY S
EASON
IS OVER, AN ESTIMATED
1.2 MILLION IDENTITIES
MAY BE STOLEN.
EVERY TIME YOU PULL OUT YOUR
WALLET, SHOP ONLINE OR HIT THE
ROAD, YOU GIVE THIEVES A CHANCE
TO RUIN YOUR HOLIDAY.
BY THE TIME YOU'RE DONE WATCHING
THIS, AS MANY AS 40 MORE
IDENTITIES MAY BE STOLEN.
YOU CAN'T BE ON THE LOOKOUT
24/7, BUT LIFELOCK CAN.
THEY'RE RELENTLESS ABOUT
PROTECTING YOUR IDENTITY
EVERY MINUTE OF EVERY DAY.
WHEN SOMEONE TRIES TO TAKE OVER
YOUR BANK ACCOUNTS, DRAIN THE
EQUITY IN YOUR HOME, OR EVEN
TRIES TO BUY A CAR IN YOUR NAME,
LIFELOCK IS ON GUARD.
AND WITH LIFELOCK'S 24/7 ALERTS,
THEY CONTACT YOU BY TEXT,
PHONE OR EMAIL AS SOON AS THEY
DETECT SUSPICIOUS ACTIVITY
IN THEIR NETWORK.
LIFELOCK WANTS YOU TO BE
PROTECTED THIS HOLIDAY SEASON,
SO THEY'RE GIVING YOU 60 DAYS
OF PROTECTION RISK-FREE.
>> MY YEARS AS A PROSECUTOR
TAUGHT ME THAT YOU HAVE TO BE
PROACTIVE TO PROTECT YOURSELF
FROM CRIME,
AND THAT'S ESPECIALLY TRUE
OF IDENTITY THEFT.
THAT'S WHY I'M A MEMBER
OF LIFELOCK.
>> Announcer: ABSOLUTELY NO ONE
PROTECTS YOU BETTER THAN
LIFELOCK, AND THEY STAND BEHIND
THEIR PROTECTION WITH THE POWER
OF THEIR $1 MILLION
SERVICE GUARANTEE.
IN FACT, LAST YEAR, LIFELOCK
PROTECTED OVER TWO MILLION
PEOPLE DURING THE HOLIDAYS.
AND NOW THEY CAN DO IT FOR YOU.
TRY LIFELOCK'S PROTECTION
60 DAYS RISK-FREE.
CALL THE NUMBER ON YOUR SCREEN
OR GO TO LIFELOCK.COM/HOLIDAYS.
IT ONLY TAKES MINUTES
TO SIGN UP.
USE PROMO CODE: HOLIDAYS.
ORDER NOW AND GET A SPECIAL
HOLIDAY GIFT: A DOCUMENT
SHREDDER TO KEEP SENSITIVE
DOCUMENTS OUT OF THE WRONG
HANDS... A $29 VALUE, FREE!
CALL THE NUMBER ON YOUR SCREEN
OR GO ONLINE AND LET LIFELOCK
PROTECT YOUR IDENTITY FOR
60 DAYS RISK-FREE.
BECAUSE DURING THE HOLIDAYS,
KEEPING YOUR IDENTITY PROTECTED
MEANS KEEPING YOUR
FAMILY PROTECTED.
Sometimes, I can't believe the
things I'm able to do.
Without Shriners Hospitals,
my life would be completely
different.
When I was seven,
we found out I had scoliosis.
Everything changed when
they stepped in.
It was like they gave me
my future back.
Tori's life is one of nearly a
million changed
by donations from people
like you.
Send your love to the rescue.
Donate today.
JENNA: WELCOME BACK,
EVERYONE.
WE HAVE BRAND NEW STORIES
COMING UP NEXT HOUR.
SOUTH CAROLINA'S GOVERNOR
EXPECTED TO NAME REPUBLICAN
REPRESENTATIVE TIM SCOTT TO
REPLACE JIM DEMINT.
HE WOULD BE THE FIRST
AFRICAN-AMERICAN GOP SENATOR
SINCE 1979.
>>> LAWMAKERS ARE LOOKING
HOW MUCH THE NORTHEAST NEEDS
TO REBUILD AFTER SUPERSTORM
SANDY.
WHY THE $60 BILLION PRICE
TAG IS BEING QUESTIONED BY
SOME.
>>> NEW VIOLENCE IN SYRIA'S
GOVERNMENT.
THE LATEST TARGET OF
MILITARY AIRSTRIKES COMING
UP NEXT HOUR.
JON: PRESIDENT OBAMA LEADING
THE NATION IN HEALING AFTER
THE CONNECTICUT SCHOOL
MASSACRE SAYING FRIDAY WAS
THE MOST DIFFICULT DAY OF
HIS PRESIDENCY.
MEETING WITH FAMILIES OF
VICTIMS BEFORE ATTENDING AN
INTERFAITH SERVICE WHERE HE
ENDED THE SPEECH SLOWLY
READING THE FIRST NAMES OF
20 CHILDREN THAT WERE KILLED
WHILE CRIES AND SOBS FILLED
THE ROOM.
KELLY WRIGHT IS LIVE AT
WHITE HOUSE THE PEEL OF
NEWTOWN OBVIOUSLY STILL IN A
STATE OF SHOCK, KELLY.
DID THE PRESIDENT'S
APPEARANCE HELP EASE THEIR
PAIN?
>> Reporter: JON, I WOULD
SAY MANY LAWMAKERS AGREE IN
FACT THE PRESIDENT'S THERE
DID BRING SOME EASING OF THE
PAIN, SOME COMFORT TO THE
FAMILIES THAT ARE STILL
DEALING WITH THIS TRAGEDY.
THE COMMANDER IN CHIEF WAS A
PARENT IN CHIEF AS HE
VISITED EACH FAMILY.
POSING IN SOME PICTURES WITH
THOSE WHO ASKED.
AS HE SPOKE TO THE COMMUNITY
THE PRESIDENT USED SCRIPTURE,
PRAYER, AND SPOKE WITH WORDS
OF COMFORT, HOPE, AND
RESOLVE.
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS I
WILL USE WHATEVER POWER THIS
OFFICE HOLDS TO ENGAGE MY
FELLOW CITIZENS FROM LAW
ENFORCEMENT TO MENTAL HEALTH
PROFESSIONALS, TO PARENTS
AND EDUCATORS IN AN EFFORT
AIMED AT PREVENTING MORE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS.
>> Reporter: THE PRESIDENT
ALSO ASKED EVERYONE IN THE
ROOM AND OF COURSE TO THE
BROADER AUDIENCE WHICH WOULD
BE THE NATION THAT WATCHED,
IF ASK YOURSELVES THIS
QUESTION.
HAVE WE DONE ENOUGH TO, TO
SAFEGUARD OUR CHILDREN FROM
ANY HARM?
AND THEN, IF YOU'RE REALLY
HONEST ABOUT IT, HE WENT ON
TO SAY, YOU WOULD HAVE TO
SAY NO.
THAT ENOUGH HAS NOT BEEN
DONE.
THAT IS WHY HE IS GOING TO
TAKE ANY MEANINGFUL ACTION
HE CAN TO CURB THIS TYPE OF
VIOLENCE.
JON: WHAT ABOUT ON CAPITOL
HILL?
WHAT ARE LAWMAKERS SAYING?
WHAT KIND OF MEANINGFUL
ACTION DO THEY WANT TO TAKE?
>> WELL THE DIALOGUE ALREADY
HAS BEGUN.
THERE ARE A QUITE A FEW
REPUBLICAN AND DEMOCRAT
LAWMAKERS COMING OUT SAYING
SOMETHING HAS TO BE DONE.
WEST VIRGINA SENATOR JOE
MANCHIN, WHO IS A DEMOCRAT
WHO IS ALSO A AVID HUNTER,
OWNS A GUN, LIFELONG MEMBER
OF THE NATIONAL RIFLE
ASSOCIATION, SAYS IT IS TIME
TO HAVE MEANINGFUL
DISCUSSIONS ABOUT THIS,
ABOUT ENACTING SOME
REASONABLE GUN CONTROL
ASPECTS OF WHO GETS A GUN,
WHO IS REQUIRED TO HAVE IT.
AND THEN YOU HAVE SENATOR
JOE LIEBERMAN OF CONNECTICUT
WHO SAYS IT IS TIME NOW TO
HAVE A MEANINGFUL DIALOGUE,
IF YOU TAKE A MEASURE TO PUT
IT THROUGH, IF IT SAVES ONE
CHILD'S LIFE IT WILL BE
WORTH IT.
>> WE'VE GOT TO BRING
EVERYBODY TO THE TABLE
INCLUDING THE GUN
MANUFACTURERS AND GUN RIGHTS
GROUPS AND ENTERTAINMENT
INDUSTRY AND JUST REGULAR
PEOPLE AND TALK ABOUT THIS,
NOT AS US AGAINST THEM BUT
THIS IS OUR NATIONAL
PROBLEM.
WE'VE GOT THE ABILITY TO, AT
LEAST MAKE SURE THAT FEWER
PEOPLE, FEWER CHILDREN
HOPEFULLY NEVER AGAIN
CHILDREN LIKE THIS, WILL BE
KILLED IN ONE OF THESE
EVENTS.
>> Reporter: JON, HERE AT
THE WHITE HOUSE THE
PRESIDENT IS WILLING
OBVIOUSLY TO HAVE THE
DIALOGUE.
THAT IS WHAT HE WILL BE
PUSHING FOR.
IN ADDITION TO THAT, WHAT HE
SAID YESTERDAY IT IS TIME
FOR THESE KINDS OF TRAGEDIES
TO STOP.
THE COUNTRY CAN'T AFFORD TO
HAVE IT ANYMORE.
HE WANTED TO SAY, I'M
QUOTING HERE, WE CAN'T
ACCEPT EVENTS LIKE THIS AS
ROUTINE.
JON: I THINK WE ALL CAN
AGREE WITH THAT.
KELLY WRIGHT AT THE
WHITE HOUSE.
THANK YOU.
JENNA: AMIDST STORIES OF
IMMENSE SADNESS ARE STORIES
OF INSPIRING ACT OF HER
ROWISM, THE PRINCIPAL OF
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG.
SHE WAS COMING OUT AFTER
MEETING WHEN SHE SAW THE
SHOOTER.
TELLING COLLEAGUES TO LOCK
THE DOOR BEHIND HER AND
LUNGED AT THE GUNMAN,
STEPPING INTO THE LINE OF
FIRE.
MARE HI SHERLACH DIED IN A
HAIL OF BULLETS.
HER FAMILY SAID SHE DIED
LOVING WHAT SHE HAD TO DO.
VICTORIA SOTO DIED SHIELDING
HER STUDENTS FROM BULLETS.
SPECIAL ED TEACHER
ANNE-MARIE MURPHY DIED
TRYING TO PROTECT THE
STUDENTS.
HER BODY WAS FOUND DEAD IN
THE CLASSROOM COVERING
CHILDREN WHO WERE ALSO
KILLED.
FIRST GRADE TEACHER CAITLIN
ROIG, PULLED A BOOKSHELF AND
LOCKED IT.
FOR REASONS THAT CAN'T BE
EXPLAINED KILLER PASSED BY
HER CLASSROOM.
JON: NEW INFORMATION OUT OF
KANSAS WHERE AN HOURS LONG
STANDOFF ENDS WITH THE DEATH
OF A MAN ACCUSED OF
MURDERING TWO POLICE
OFFICERS.
HEATHER NOW ART HAS THE
LATEST.
>> Reporter: IN EARLY
MORNING HOURS TOPEKA POLICE
RESPONDED TO A SHOOTING THAT
TOOK THE LIVES OF THEIR OWN
POLICE OFFICERS.
POLICE SURROUNDED THE HOUSE
IN NEARLY TWO HOUR STANDOFF
WHEN SHOTS WERE FIRED.
THIS MORNING OUR LOCAL FOX
AFFILIATE THAT THE SUSPECTS
IN THE OFFICERS KILLINGS,
22-YEAR-OLD, DAVID EVIDENCE
WARD.
TOSCARINO WHO HAS A CRIMINAL
RECORD IS DEAD.
WHEN HE TRIED TO LEAVE THE
HOUSE, OFFICERS FIRED SHOTS
THAT KILLED HIM.
THIS STARTED 6 P.M. SUNDAY
NIGHT.
POLICE RESPONDED TO A CALL
ABOUT A SUSPICIOUS VEHICLE
OUTSIDE THE GROCERY STORE.
THREE OFFICERS ARRIVED AT
THE SCENE.
50-YEAR-OLD, DAVID GOGIAN
AND 29-YEAR-OLD-YEAR-OLD
JEFF ATHERLY, APPROACHED THE
CAR CONTAINING THE HIM AND
OTHER PASSENGERS, THAT'S
WHEN SHOTS WERE FIRED
KILLING THE OFFICERS.
>> ALWAYS SAD WHEN OFFICER
GETTING INJURED.
WE PROTECT PEOPLE.
WHEN AN OFFICER IS HURT,
THAT IS HARD THING.
>> Reporter: GOGIAN WAS
SUPERVISOR WITH THE TOPEKA
POLICE DEPARTMENT.
HE SERVED THE COMMUNITY
EIGHT YEARS WHEN HE GOT OUT
OF THE MILITARY.
ATHERLY, WAS BEGINNING HIS
CAREER IN THE DEPARTMENT.
HE SERVED A YEAR AND A HALF.
OFFICERS ARE EXECUTING OTHER
SEARCH WARRANTS IN THE AREA.
THEY'RE NOT SAYING THEY'RE
LOOKING FOR OTHER SUSPECTS
AT THE TIME.
POLICE HOLDING A PRESS
CONFERENCE AT 2:00 P.M.
EASTERN TIME TODAY.
THAT'S WHEN WE EXPECT TO
LEARN MORE.
WE'LL BRING THAT TO YOU.
JON.
JON: APPARENTLY THERE WERE
OTHER PEOPLE IN THE CAR FROM
WHICH THE SHOTS ORIGINALLY
CAME?
>> Reporter: THAT'S RIGHT.
THEY SAID THEY'RE NOT
LOOKING FOR ANYBODY ELSE
WHICH SOUNDS CURE US WHY.
WE'LL LOOK INTO THAT TO SEE
WHAT THEY HAVE TO SAY.
JON: THANK YOU.
HEATHER NAUERT.
JENNA: INVESTIGATORS ARE
SEEKING TO LEARN MORE ABOUT
ADAM LANZA THE MURDERER IN
THE CONNECTICUT SCHOOL
MASSACRE.
THEY'RE POURING OVER
EVIDENCE FROM TWO SEPARATE
CRIME SCENES.
WHAT INVESTIGATORS HOPE TO
FIND AND WHAT IS A REALISTIC
EXPECTATION ACTUALLY HAVING
ANY SORT OF ANSWERS IN THIS
CASE?
>>> CALLS FOR MASS PROTEST
IN EGYPT BEFORE THE FINAL
PHASE OF VOTING THERE.
THIS AFTER PRESIDENT MORSI
RACKED UP NEW SUPPORT IN
WHAT SOME ARE CALLING HIS
POWER GRAB.
WE'LL HAVE THE LIVE STORY
AHEAD.
[SHOUTING]
JENNA: WELCOME BACK,
EVERYONE.
WE'RE AWAITING A POLICE
UPDATE ON THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL MASSACRE.
OFFICIALS TOLD US EARLIER
TODAY THEY BELIEVE THEY HAVE
MONTHS OF WORK AHEAD OF THEM
IN THIS INVESTIGATION AS
THEY TRY TO FIGURE OUT WHAT
LED ADAM LANZA TO GO ON THIS
DEADLY RAMPAGE.
RIGHT NOW THEY'RE GATHERING
EVIDENCE FROM TWO SEPARATE
CRIME SCENES INCLUDING HIS
HOME AS WELL AS THE SCHOOL
WHICH WILL REMAIN CLOSED
INDEFINITELY.
>> WE ARE HOLDING BOTH CRIME
SCENES, THE SCHOOL, AND THE
SECONDARY CRIME SCENE,
INDEFINITELY.
WE'VE SEIZED IT UNDER SEARCH
WARRANTS AND WE'RE GOING TO
HOLD THOSE LOCATIONS UNTIL
WE HAVE COMPLETED OUR WORK
AND WE FEEL IT IS
APPROPRIATE TO LET THEM GO.
SO AS NOT TO READ ANYTHING
INTO THAT, IT IS COMMON
PRACTICE TO DO THAT, TO HOLD
ONTO THE CRIME SCENE, AS
LONG AS IT IS NEEDED FOR
INVESTIGATORY PURPOSES.
JENNA: JOINING US NOW THE
CEO OF BROSNAN RISK
CONSULTANTS AND FORMER NYPD
DETECTIVE THAT INVESTIGATED
MANY CRIME SCENES, PAT, IN
YOUR CAREER.
I WANT TO START WITH A
LITTLE NEWS WE GOT.
ONE OF OUR PRODUCERS OUTSIDE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
SEEN A MOVING VAN COME UP TO
THE SCHOOL.
LOOKS LIKE THEY'RE REMOVING
DESKS AND CHAIRS AT THIS
TIME.
WHY WOULD THEY BE DOING THAT
NOW?
>> IT IS PART OF AN ACTIVE
AND VERY COMPLEX CRIME
SCENE.
THEY MAKING CHAIRS AND DESKS
STRUGGLE BY BULLET FRAGMENTS,
PART OF THE CRIME SCENE FOR
ANALYSIS TO OUTSIDE LAB.
JENNA: WHY WOULD YOU REMOVE
IT?
WHY WOULD YOU REMOVE IT TO
OUTSIDE LAB AND NOT LOOK AT
IT IN THE CRIME SCENE AS IT
IS?
>> WELL THEY HAVE EXAMINED
FORSENICALLY AT THE LAB TO
MAINTAIN CUSTODY AND CONTROL
OF THE EVIDENCE.
IT WOULD HAVE TO BE A
FORENSIC STAND ALONE LAB.
IN OTHER WORDS, THEY LOOK AT
TIE IT TOGETHER AT THE CRIME
SCENE BUT FOR FORENSIC
PURPOSES IN TERMS OF
DEVELOPING AND
SCIENTIFICALLY WOULD BE DONE
EXTERNALLY AT A THIRD PARTY
LAB.
JENNA: SPEAKING OF SCHOOL.
EMPTY ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
NO ONE IS THERE.
NO VICTIMS ARE THERE.
YOU'RE WALKING INTO THIS
SCENE, PAT.
WHERE DO YOU EVEN BEGIN AS
AN INVESTIGATOR?
>> WELL, THIS OBVIOUSLY IS
THE HORROR AMONGST HORRORS.
WE KNOW THAT IS WELL STOOESHED.
BUT INORDINANTLY COMPLEX
CRIME SCENE WITH MANY MOVING
PARTS.
THERE ARE FACTORS BEYOND RYE
APPROACH.
WE KNOW HOW MANY SHOTS WERE
FIRED AND VICTIMS.
HE LEFT HUNDREDS OF BULLETS.
EACH ONE HAS A STORY TO
TELL.
THEY WANT TO EXAMINE THOSE
BULLETS GOING BACK FROM
THEIR BIRTH, ON THE
GUNSMITH'S TABLE TO THE
DECEMBER 14th AT 9:30 A.M.
CRITICAL.
JENNA: LET ME RETURN TO THAT
POINT IN A SECOND BECAUSE WE
JUST GOT THIS VIDEO IN.
YOU CAN SEE ON THE SCREEN,
THESE ARE HUGE MOVING VANS
AS YOU MENTIONED, PAT, TO
OUR VIEWERS.
YOU THINK SOME OF THESE
DESKS AND CHAIRS,
POTENTIALLY FURNITURE COMING
OUT OF THE CLASSROOM MIGHT
CONTAIN BULLETS AND THAT IS
WHAT THEY WILL LOOK AT.
GO BACK TO THE CRITICAL
ST BULLET CAN
TELL US.
WITH SO MUCH MATERIAL WE
BELIEVE THAT IS THERE AND
OFFICIALS HAVE ALLUDED TO,
HOW DO YOU BRING IT TOGETHER
AND WHAT REALLY IS A
REALISTIC TIMELINE FOR ANY
SORT OF ANSWERS THAT IT
COULD PROVIDE?
>> WELL TO START THE LAST
QUESTION A TIMELINE IS
IMPOSSIBLE TO SPECULATE.
INORDINANTLY COMPLEX CASE.
HE FIRED HUNDREDS OF
BULLETS.
THAT ALONE IS VERY UNUSUAL
AND COMPOUNDS THE TRAGEDY
EXPONENTIALLY.
BUT THE FACT IS EACH ONE OF
THOSE BULLETS, EACH AND
EVERYONE IS STAND ALONE
PIECE OF EVIDENTIARY
MATERIAL.
HAS TO BE FORSENICALLY
ANALYZED.
TESTED AGAINST RIVALLING OF
BULLETS, RIFLING OF WEAPONS,
AND HAS TO BE RESEARCH WHEN
IT CAME TO BIRTH, WHEN THAT
BULLET CAME TO LIFE UNTIL
THE BULLET WAS USED ON THE
14th.
THERE MAY BE OTHER
SHOOTINGS.
JENNA: HOW INTERESTING.
>> YOU HAVE TO ALWAYS PUT
THE EYE TOWARD OTHER
COLLATERAL SHOOTINGS.
>> MIGHT HAVE TO KEEP YOUR
MIND OPEN AT A TIME LIKE
THIS.
>> PRECISELY.
SAME WITH WEAPONS TOO,
JENNA.
THOSE WEAPONS HAVE TO BE
LOOKED AT VERY CLOSELY WHEN
THEY LEFT THE GUNSMITH'S
TABLE UNTIL THEY --.
JENNA: TALKING A LOT ABOUT
FRIENDSIC EVIDENCE.
ONE OF THE THINGS PAUL VANCE
BROUGHT UP AS WELL DURING
THE NEWS CONFERENCE THE
INTERVIEWING OF WITNESSES
AND ONE OF THE THINGS HE
SAID THEY WILL BE
INTERVIEWING CHILDREN.
>> YES.
JENNA: HOW DO YOU DO THAT,
PAT?
>> WITH EXTRAORDINARY
DELICACY, EXTREME
SENSITIVITY.
VERY, VERY, SLOWLY IN THE
PRESENCE OF THE PARENTS AND
WITH HIGHLY, HIGHLY SKILLED,
SPECIALIZED INVESTIGATORS
WHO HAVE CONDUCTED THOSE
LEVELS OF INTERVIEWS BEFORE.
JENNA: DO YOU START NOW,
WAIT A COUPLE WEEKS, WHEN DO
YOU DO IT?
>> I DON'T THINK THEY WILL
START NOW.
INTERESTINGLY, MY EXPERIENCE
WITH INTERVIEWING VERY YOUNG
CHILDREN THEY ARE GREAT
WITNESSES BOTH EARWITNESSES
AND EYEWITNESSES.
>> REALLY?
>> BECAUSE THEIR RECALL IS
NOT INFLUENCED BY BASELINE
HISTORY OF OTHER EVENTS.
THEY'RE BRAND NEW.
THEY'RE YOUNG.
THEY DON'T HAVE A WHOLE LOT
IN THEIR MEMORIES.
IT IS VERY SAD WAY TO LOOK
AT IT BUT VERY PRAGMATIC WAY
TO LOOK AT I.
THEY MAKE GREAT WITNESSES.
EVERYTHING IS UNVARNISHED
EVERYTHING IS TRUE.
NO AGENDA WITH THE SMALL
FRIES.
THEY DON'T HAVE AN AGENDA.
WHEN TEASE OUT THE
INFORMATION, DELICATELY
EXTRACT THE INFORMATION
PIECE BY PIECE IT COULD BE
VERY VITAL DATA.
JENNA: UNDERSCORES THE
SADNESS WE FEEL ABOUT THEIR
LIVES.
>> TOTALLY.
JENNA: HOW INNOCENT THEY
ARE.
>> WORST EVER.
JENNA: PAT, THANK YOU.
>> YOU'RE WELCOME.
JENNA: I APPRECIATE YOU
WALKING US THROUGH THIS AS
WE TRY TO WRAP OUR MIND
AROUND IT SOMEHOW AND SEARCH
FOR ANSWERS SOMEHOW IN THIS
CASE.
THANK YOU AGAIN.
>> YOU'RE WELCOME.
JENNA: JON?
JON: RIGHT NOW IN EGYPT
TENSIONS ARE ON THE RISE AS
RIVAL GROUPS OPPOSING THE
GOVERNMENT ARE CALLING FOR
MASS PROTESTS TOMORROW.
THIS AFTER SUPPORTERS OF
PRESIDENT MOHAMMED MORSI,
THE MUSLIM BROTHERHOOD, CAMED --
CLAIMED VICTORY IN THE FIRST
ROUND OF VOTING ON MORSI'S
DRAFT CONSTITUTION.
THIS TOOK PLACE OVER THE
WEEKEND.
GREG PALKOT STREAMING LIVE
FROM KEY OWE EGYPT.
GREG?
>> Reporter: HEY, JON, YEAH.
FOLKS ARE A LITTLE BIT ON
EDGE OFF VOTING OVER THE
WEEKEND ON THE DRAFT
CONSTITUTION.
THE RESULTS WERE CLOSER THAN
EXPECTED.
THE YES VOTES WERE 57%.
NO, 43%.
THE TURNOUT WAS LOWER THAN
USUAL.
ACCORDING TO THE OPPOSITION
THE VOTE WAS MARCHED BY
MAURED BY WIDESPREAD
IRREGULARITIS.
OPPOSITION ATTACKING
OPPOSITION HEADQUARTERS HERE
IN CAIRO.
ALL THAT IS PROMPTING AGAIN
BY GOVERNMENT CRITICS WHO
CALLED FOR MORE PROTESTS ON
TUESDAY, IN FRONT.
PRESIDENTIAL PALACE IN
TAHRIR SQUARE BEHIND ME AND
UP TO THE U.S. EMBASSY.
THIS IS UP TO THE SECOND AND
FINAL ROUND OF VOTING IN
RURAL AREAS OF EGYPT ON
SATURDAY FOR THE
CONSTITUTION WHICH IS
FAVORED BY EGYPTIAN
PRESIDENT MOHAMMED MORSI AND
HIS MUSLIM BROTHERHOOD
PARTY.
CRITICS SAY IT IS TOO
ISLAMIST.
DEFENDERS SAY IT IS
NECESSARY TO PRESERVE
STABILITY HERE IN THIS
COUNTRY.
ANALYSTS ARE SAYING THEY
EXPECT THE CONSTITUTION TO
BE APPROVED.
WHILE IT CAN BE MODIFIED
AFTERWARDS AND WILL PAVE THE
WAY TO NEW ELECTIONS FOR A
NEW PARLIAMENT, THESE LATEST
RESULTS ARE SEEN AS WIDENING
THE DIVIDE BETWEEN THE TWO
SIDES.
THAT OF COURSE KEEPING VERY
MUCH ALIVE THE THREAT OF YET
MORE VIOLENCE AND OF COURSE
THE CHALLENGE OF RUNNING
THIS COUNTRY.
BACK TO YOU.
JON: WE MAY BE LOOKING AT
MORE TROUBLE THERE.
GREG PALKOT REPORTING LIVE
FROM CAIRO.
THANK YOU.
JENNA: THE MURDERS IN
NEWTOWN PUTTING A NEW FOCUS
ON TREATING MENTAL HEALTH
DISORDERS.
WE'LL TALK A LITTLE ABOUT
THAT COMING UP.
THE WARNING SIGNS AND ALSO
POTENTIALLY WHAT CAN BE DONE
TO IMPROVE BETTER ACCESS TO
CARE.
THAT INDEED PART OF THE
STORY WE DO NOT KNOW NOW
THERE ARE SOME QUESTIONS
THAT REMAIN ABOUT ADAM LANZA.
>>> NEW ATROCITIES
REPORTEDLY COMMITTED BY THE
GOVERNMENT IN SYRIA.
WE'RE JOINED BY A REPORTER
WHO HAD A FIRST-HAND LOOK
WHAT IS HAPPENING NOW.
I ALWAYS WAIT
UNTIL THE LAST MINUTE.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME R CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
FLAVOR BOOST, MEET BEEF.
IT'S SWANSON FLAVOR BOOST.
CONCENTRATED BROTH
TO ADD DELICIOUS FLAVOR
TO YOUR SKILLET DISH
IN JUST ONE STIR.
MMM!
[ Female Announcer ]
COOK, MEET COMPLIMENTS.
GET RECIPES AT FLAVORBOOST.COM.
JENNA: BRING YOU OUT TO
FLORIDA NOW.
THIS IS A LIVE SHOT OF A
RESCUE TAKING PLACE.
THE HELICOPTER JUST LANDED
IN THIS AREA IN MIAMI-DADE
COUNTY BECAUSE THERE WAS A
PERSON REPORTEDLY STUCK
UNDER A PIECE OF EQUIPMENT
AT A CONSTRUCTION SITE.
IN FACT WE MIGHT HAVE VIDEO
OF THAT FOR YOU AS WELL.
WE DON'T KNOW MUCH ABOUT THE
INCIDENT.
WE KNOW AGAIN THIS WORKER,
AND YOU'RE SEEING THIS
PERSON WHEELED OUT ON A
STRETCHER RIGHT NOW,
APPARENTLY STUCK UNDER A
PIECE OF EQUIPMENT.
SOME INITIAL REPORTS SAY, IT
MIGHT BE A STEAM ROLLER.
WE'LL WORK ON SOME MORE
INFORMATION AS WE GET IT BUT
RIGHT NOW A RESCUE UNDERWAY
IN MIAMI-DADE COUNTY DOWN IN
FLORIDA.
THE CONSTRUCTION WORKER
POTENTIALLY BEING PULLED OUT
FROM UNDERNEATH A STEAM
ROLLER.
MORE INFORMATION AS WE GET
IT.
JON: THE TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN
REOPENS THE DEBATE WHAT TO
DO ABOUT MENTAL ILLNESS IN
THIS COUNTRY.
SADLY IT SEEMS TO BE A
COMMON DENOMINATOR IN SO
MANY MASS SHOOTINGS IN
RECENT YEARS.
THE BROTHER OF SHOOTER ADAM
LANZA REPORTEDLY TELLING
POLICE HIS BROTHER SUFFERS
FROM ASPERGER'S SYNDROME AND
HE HAD A PERSONALITY
DISORDER.
JAMES HOLMES THE SHOOTER IN
LAST SUMMER'S MOVIE THEATER
SHOOTING WAS KNOWN TO HAVE
PSYCHOLOGICAL PROBLEMS.
JARED LOUGHNER WHO TRIED TO
ASSASSINATE GABRIEL GIFFORDS
HAD LONG BEEN SUSPECTED OF
BEING UNSTABLE.
WHEN HE WAS ARRESTED AND PUT
ON TRIAL HE WAS DEEMED AT
FIRST UNFIT TO STAND TRIAL.
DR. LEE VINOCUR, BOARD
CERTIFIED PHYSICIAN, ADJUNCT
ASSISTANT PROFESSOR AT
LIEUTENANT STATE UNIVERSITY
MEDICAL SCHOOL?
SHREVEPORT.
DOCTOR, AT TIMES LIKE THIS I
THINK BACK TO WHAT MY HIGH
SCHOOL PRINCIPAL ONCE TAUGHT
ME WHICH THE BRAIN IS ORGAN
LIKE ANY OTHER IN THE BODY.
JUST LIKE ANY OTHER IT CAN
GET SICK.
>> YEAH.
ABSOLUTELY, IT IS JUST
TERRIBLE THAT WE HAVE TO
HAVE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS WE
HAVE A MENTAL HEALTH CRISIS
TODAY IN THE UNITED STATES.
IN THE LAST DECADE SERVICES
HAVE SHRUNK, PSYCHIATRIC
HOSPITALS HAVE CLOSED.
AND THE E.R. UNFORTUNATELY
KNOWS VERY WELL THAT WHEN
THERE'S A CRISIS RELATED TO
MENTAL HEALTH, EVERYBODY
ENDS UP IN THE E.R. AND IT
BACKS UP THE E.R. BECAUSE WE
HAVE NO PLACE TO SEND THESE
PEOPLE FOR MORE DEFINITIVE
HELP AFTER THE CRISIS.
IT IS A BIG PROBLEM.
JON: WHY IS THAT, AS A
SOCIETY WE HAVE CLOSED DOWN
SO MANY OF THESE MENTAL
HEALTH CENTERS AND SO FORTH?
>> WELL, I THINK, YOU KNOW,
SOME OF IT IS BUDGET TERRI
OF COURSE.
I MEAN PEOPLE ARE CUTTING
AND, HOSPITALS DEDICATED
STRICTLY TO PSYCHIATRIC
ISSUES HAVE JUST BEEN
SQUEEZED LIKE OTHER
HOSPITALS AND ALSO, IF YOU
THINK ABOUT SOMETIMES THE
PEOPLE WITH, THERE'S A
STIGMA ABOUT MENTAL HEALTH.
THE INDIGENT, SOMETIMES
THERE IS NOT A LOT OF
INSURANCE COVERAGE FOR IT
AND, IT IS JUST PUT A BIG
SQUEEZE ON E.R.S THAT ARE
THE SAFETY NET NOW FOR
MENTAL HEALTH.
THEY GET BACKED UP BECAUSE
THERE IS NO PLACE TO SEND
PEOPLE THAT NEED EXTENDED
CARE.
JON: THE REPORT THAT THE
GUNMAN HAD ASPERGER'S
SYNDROME, IT IS NOT A COMMON
CONDITION BUT THERE ARE A
LOT OF PEOPLE IN THIS
COUNTRY WHO HAVE ASPERGER'S
SYNDROME AND THEY'RE NOT
RUNNING OUT PICKING UP GUNS
AND FIRING INTO CLASSROOMS?
>> THAT IS BIG ISSUE.
ASPERGER'S IS ON THE AUTISM
SPECTRUM.
HE WAS REPORTED EXTREMELY
SHY.
A LOT OF PEOPLE WITH
ASPERGERS ARE VERY SOCIAL
BUT THERE IS QUIRKINESS TO
THEM WHEN YOU START TO TALK
TO THEM.
CERTAINLY ASPERGER'S IS NOT
PREDISPOSITION TO THAT.
YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW, A
PATIENT COMES INTO THE E.R.
WITH A MENTAL HEALTH DYING
MOST SIS OR ILLNESS, YOU
NEED TO DECIDE AT THE TIME
ARE THEY A RISK TO
THEMSELVES OR OTHERS AND YOU
CAN NEVER FULLY PREDICT WHEN
SOMETHING LIKE THIS IS GOING
TO HAPPEN, WHEN SOMEONE IS
GOING TO BECOME VIOLENT,
WHEN THEY'RE GOING TO SNAP.
THAT'S A BIG ISSUE, BUT
CERTAINLY IF WE DEALT MORE
PREVENTATIVELY, MORE
OUTPATIENT THERAPY FOR
MENTAL HEALTH PEOPLE, MORE
INPATIENT BEDS FOR PATIENTS
IN CRISIS, SO THEY DON'T GET
TURNED OUT ON THE STREET YOU
WOULD LESSEN THE CHANCES OF
SOME KIND OF VIOLENT
SNAPPING OR SOME KIND OF
VIOLENT INCIDENT.
JON: SO MANY LESSONS HERE
STILL TO BE FIGURED OUT.
WE'RE STILL IN THE EARLY
STAGES OF DOING THAT.
OBVIOUSLY A LOT OF DECISIONS
NEED TO BE MADE.
MAYBE SOME SYSTEMS CHANGED.
DR. VINOCUR, THANK YOU.
>> MY PLEASURE.
JENNA: A CHANGE OF COMMAND
IN THE SENATE.
SENATOR DEMINT WILL BE
LEAVING AND WE'RE HEARING
NOW SOUTH CAROLINA
CONGRESSMAN TIM SCOTT IS
GETTING THE NOD TO TAKE HIS
PLACE, A HISTORIC MOVE.
WE'LL HAVE THE LATEST AT THE
TOP OF THE HOUR.
>>> ALSO WE'RE AWAITING A
NEWS CONFERENCE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WHERE POLICE
WILL UPDATE US ON THE VERY
LATEST IN THE INVESTIGATION.
WE'LL BRING THAT TO YOU LIVE
AS SOON AS IT STARTS TOP OF
THE HOUR.
♪ .
WE'VE DIDED TO
PUT ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
'CAUSE ALL OUR STATES ARE GREAT.
AND NOW IS WHEN THE GULF
GETS EVEN BETT.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE OR
JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
ENJOY THE WILDLIFE
AND NATURAL BEAUTY.
AND DON'T FORGET
OUR AMAZING SEAFOOD.
SOOME TO THE GULF,
YOU'LL HAVE A GREAT TIME.
ESPECIALLY IN ALABAMA.
YOU MEAN MISSISSIPPI.
THAT'S FLORIDA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP AND ALL
OF US WHO CA THE GULF HOME.
JENNA: WE'RE AWAITING A NEWS
CONFERENCE, HOPEFULLY SOME MORE
INFORMATION FROM POLICE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
IN THE MEANTIME, THE FIRST OF
TWO FUNERALS ARE ABOUT TO GET
UNDERWAY.
WE'RE GLAD YOU'RE WITH US ON
THIS MONDAY MORNING, I'M JENNA
LEE.
JON: I'M JON SCOTT.
A DARK SHADOW HANGS OVER THE
NORMALLY JOYFUL HOLIDAY SEASON
AS TWO FAMILIES PREPARE TO BURY
TEAR CHILDREN.
THEIR CHILDREN.
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE ARE
ABOUT TO GIVE AN UPDATE ON THE
LATEST IN THEIR INVESTIGATION.
WHEN THEY TEN TO THE
MICROPHONES, WE WILL TAKE YOU
THERE LIVE.
PLUS, TWO FUNERALS TAKING PLACE
TODAY BEGINNING ABOUT AN HOUR
FROM NOW.
6-YEAR-OLD JACK PINTO, A NEW
YORK GIANTS FAN, AND NOAH
POSNER, ALSO 6, WHO LIKED TO
FIGURE OUT HOW THINGS WORK
MECHANICALLY.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT THE
STATUS OF THE INVESTIGATION?
>> Reporter: JON, NOAH WAS
JUST BORN IN 2006 AS 16 OF THE
VICTIMS WERE, AND ABOUT AN HOUR
AND A HALF AGO, WE GOT AN UPDATE
INTO THE INVESTIGATION INTO
THEIR MURDER.
AUTHORITIES ARE SAYING THAT
BEFORE FRIDAY THEY HAD NO
CONTACT WITH ADAM LANZA.
HE WAS NOT A KNOWN CRIMINAL
AROUND NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
AUTHORITIES ARE ALSO SAYING THAT
THEY ARE RIGHT NOW INTERVIEWING
MANY, MANY WITNESSES INCLUDING A
LOT OF KIDS WHO ESCAPED THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL ON FRIDAY.
WE'RE TOLD BY THE AUTHORITIES
THAT THOSE INTERVIEWS ARE GOING
TO BE DONE DELICATELY WITH THEIR
PARENTS BY THEIR SIDE.
THIS IS HAPPENING WHILE MAJOR
CRIMES DETECTIVES ARE WORKING
AROUND THE CLOCK, 24-HOUR DAYS,
TO TO TRACE THE WEAPONS THAT
WERE USED BACK TO THE ASSEMBLY
LINE, ALL THE WAY BACK.
THEY WANT TO KNOW EVERYWHERE
THOSE WEAPONS HAVE BEEN.
THEY'RE ALSO GOING TO ANALYZE
HUNDREDS OF ROUNDS OF AMMUNITION
FROM MULTIPLE
>> THE WEAPONRY EVERY SINGLE
FACET OF THE WEAPONS WILL BE
ORGANIZED, LOOKED AT AND
EXAMINED FOR EVERY KIND OF
PHYSICAL EVIDENCE.
I ALLUDED YESTERDAY TO THE
VOLUME OF ROUNDS, FOR EXAMPLE,
THAT, IN FACT, WERE SEIZED OR
RECOVERED.
EACH SINGULAR ROUND WILL BE
EXAMINED.
>> Reporter: AND, JON, AROUND
HERE THE FOCUS IS ON ALL OF THE
YOUNG VICTIMS LIKE ANNA GRACE
MARQUEZ GREEN.
SHE WAS 6 YEARS OLD, AND HER
PARENTS ARE SAYING SHE NEVER
WALKED ANYWHERE BECAUSE HER MODE
OF TRANSPORTATION WAS DANCE.
JON: UNBELIEVABLE.
SO MUCH SADNESS.
SO OF THE GUNMAN'S NUCLEAR
FAMILY, HALF OF THEM ARE DEAD
NOW.
WHAT HAVE WE LEARNED ABOUT THE
FAMILY?
>> Reporter: JON, THIS MORNING
WE SAW THE DIVORCE PAPERS
BETWEEN, FROM A DIVORCE A FEW
YEARS BACK BETWEEN NANCY AND
PETER LANZA.
THERE REALLY ARE NO SIGNS OF
BITTERNESS IN IT.
NANCY GOT ALMOST $290,000 IN
ALIMONY THIS YEAR, AND THEY DID
HAVE JOINT CUSTODY, BUT ADAM
LANZA LIVED WITH HIS MOTHER
NANCY HERE IN NEWTOWN.
IT'S INTERESTING, ONE OF NANCY'S
FRIENDS WHO I SPOKE TO THIS
MORNING TOLD ME THAT, IN HIS
OPINION, HE HAS A SON WITH A
SIMILAR DISORDER, WITH A
SIMILAR -- HE HAS A SON WHO'S
AUTISTIC, AND HE SAID HE USED TO
BOND WITH NANCY LANZA ABOUT THE
DIFFICULTIES OF RAISING A CHILD
WITH A DISORDER LIKE THAT.
AND HE SAID THAT HE THINKS THAT
AS A SINGLE MOTHER SHE WAS NOT
EQUIPPED TO DEAL WITH HIS
ISSUES.
LISTEN TO THIS.
>> YEAH.
SHE WAS TRYING TO BOND, FIND
WAYS TO BOND WITH HIM, AND, YOU
KNOW, SHE TOLD ME THAT THE GUNS,
YOU KNOW, SHE WOULD TAKE THEM
SHOOTING BECAUSE THAT WAS OF OF
A WAY THAT, YOU KNOW, A SINGLE
MOM COULD, YOU KNOW, RELATE TO
HER SON.
AND SO SHE WOULD TAKE HIM, TAKE
HIM OUT SHOOTING.
>> Reporter: WE'VE BEEN
GETTING A LOT OF INFORMATION,
JON, FROM THE AUTHORITIES AND
FROM FRIENDS OF THE, OF EVERYONE
INVOLVED X WE DO EXPECT AN
UPDATE ANY MINUTE NOW.
JON: YEAH.
THAT UPDATE SCHEDULED TO BEGIN,
AS YOU SAY, ANYTIME NOW.
PETER DOOCY IN NEWTOWN, THANK
YOU.
JENNA: IT'S UNCLEAR IF SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY WILL EVER REOPEN
O.
TOWN OFFICIALS ARE CONSIDERING A
PLAN TO SEND STUDENTS TO A
FORMER SCHOOL BUILDING JUST
MILES AWAY.
WE'VE HEARD THAT.
ALSO MAYBE THEY'LL BE SENT TO
ANOTHER SCHOOL DISTRICT.
IT COULD BE MONTHS BEFORE THE
SCHOOL IS RELEASED BACK TO THE
DISTRICT.
>> WE ARE HOLDING BOTH CRIME
SCENES, THE SCHOOL AND THE
SECOND DARE CRIME SCENE --
SECONDARY CRIME SCENE,
INDEFINITELY.
WE'VE SEIZED IT UNDER SEARCH
WARRANTS, AND WE'RE GOING TO
HOLD THOSE UNTIL WE FEEL IT'S
APPROPRIATE TO LET THEM GO.
SO AS NOT TO READ ANYTHING INTO
THAT, IT IS COMMON PRACTICE TO
DO THAT, TO HOLD ON TO THE CRIME
SCENE AS LONG AS IT'S NEEDED FOR
INVESTIGATORY PURPOSES.
JENNA: BRIAN WAS EL HAS TREATED
CHILDREN AFTER TRAUMA WHICH IS,
I'M SURE, AN INCREDIBLE TASK,
DR. RUSSELL.
IN THIS TYPE OF SITUATION FOR
THAT CHILDREN THAT EITHER HAVE
WITNESSED THIS EVENT OR WERE AT
THE SCHOOL AT THE TIME, WHAT'S
IN THEIR BEST INTERESTS?
IS IT TO RETURN TO THE BUILDING
WHERE THIS TOOK PLACE?
WHAT'S BEST FOR THEM?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, JENNA, WE
TALKED ABOUT A LOT OF THESE SAME
THINGS AFTER KOHL M WINE, AND
IT'S REALLY SORT OF PREMATURE TO
BE TALKING ABOUT THE LONG-TERM
FUTURE OF THAT BUILDING.
OBVIOUSLY, IN THE SHORT TERM IT
IS A CRIME SCENE, AND IT'S GOING
TO NEED TO BE KEPT THAT WAY FOR
EVIDENTIARY GATHERING PURPOSES.
I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT TO KEEP
IN MIND THAT LOTS OF KIDS AROUND
THE COUNTRY, EVEN THOSE
INDIRECTLY AFFECTED BY THE
COVERAGE OF THIS, MAY NEED SOME
ATTENTION.
BUT IT'S HARD TO GENERALIZE THE
KIND.
KIDS ARE VERY RESILIENT, THAT'S
THE GOOD NEWS, AND IT'S HARD TO
SAY EXACTLY HOW EACH INDIVIDUAL
KID IS GOING TO BE AFFECTED,
BECAUSE IT'S A VERY
INDIVIDUALIZED THING.
SOME GENERAL TIPS FOR
PARTICIPANTS WOULD BE TO LISTEN
TO -- FOR PARENTS WOULD BE TO
LISTEN TO THEIR KIDS.
KIDS MAY NOT HAVE BEEN AS
AFFECTED AS A PARENT MAY ASSUME,
AND THEY CAN MINIMIZE THE
FURTHER EFFECTS BY NOT HAVING
THIS ALL OVER THE TV ON THEIR
HOUSE ALL DAY LONG, TO VALIDATE
WHATEVER FEELINGS THE KIDS ARE
HAVING ABOUT IT AND REASSURE
THEM.
THIS THREATENS KIDS' SENSE THAT
THEIR WORLD WITH PREDICTABLE AND
SAFE AND SECURE AND STABLE.
YOU COULD REFOCUS YOUR KIDS OFF
OF THE GORY DETAILS AND ON TO
THE POSITIVE ASPECTS LIKE THE
HEROISM OF THE FIRST RESPONDERS
AND SOME OF THE STAFF THERE.
AND THEN YOU CAN TAKE SOME
ACTION LIKE MAYBE TAKE YOUR KIDS
WITH YOU IF YOU GIVE BLOOD, OR
MAKE SOME CHRISTMAS COOKIES AND
TAKE THEM TO THE FIRST
RESPONDERS IN YOUR AREAS THAT
THE ADULTS, THE GOOD GUYS ARE
BACK IN CHARGE.
AND IF NONE OF THAT SEEMS TO BE
WORKING, SEEK OUT A MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONAL IN YOUR
COMMUNITY.
THAT'S WHAT THEY'RE THERE FOR.
JENNA: SO MANY OF US CARE ABOUT
THIS COMMUNITY NOW AND WANT TO
HELP IN ANY WAY THAT WE CAN.
FOR THE CHILDREN THERE, I KNOW
WE DON'T WANT TO THINK TOO LONG
TERM, BUT HOW IMPORTANT IS IT
FOR THEM TO STAY TOGETHER, TO
NOT BE SPLIT UP?
BECAUSE THEY'RE GOING TO HAVE TO
RETURN TO SCHOOL EVENTUALLY, AND
PROBABLY IN NOT TOO DISTANT
FUTURE THAT THEY'RE GOING TO
HAVE TO RETURN THE TO SCHOOL.
SO WHAT WOULD BE YOUR SUGGESTION
THERE?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, YOU MAKE A
GREAT POINT.
NOT EVERYBODY NEEDS TO RUN
STRAIGHT TO PSYCHOTHERAPY AFTER
A TRAUMA, BUT WHAT VIRTUALLY
EVERYBODY NEEDS IS A SOCIAL
SUPPORT SYSTEM.
AND FOR THESE KIDS, THEIR FELLOW
STUDENTS WHO WENT THROUGH THIS
WITH THEM, ARE SORT OF NATURAL
SOCIAL SUPPORT SYSTEM.
SO I WOULD SAY THAT FIRST AND
FOREMOST THE IMPORTANT THING IS
THAT EACH AND EVERY ONE OF THOSE
KIDS HAS A SOCIAL SUPPORT
SYSTEM.
AND TO THE EXTENT THAT IT CAN
INCLUDE EACH OTHER, I THINK THAT
THAT'S PROBABLY ON BALANCE MORE
OF A BENEFIT.
BUT I DON'T THINK IF ONE OF
THOSE PARENTS, FOR EXAMPLE,
FEELS LIKE THEY NEED TO MOVE OUT
OF THAT COMMUNITY, THAT THAT'S
SOMEHOW GOING TO, YOU KNOW,
PREDISPOSE THEIR CHILD TO BE
DAMAGED WORSE IN THE LONG RUN.
JENNA: YOU PICK UP ON SOMETHING
REALLY IMPORTANT THERE AS WELL
BECAUSE SO MANY OF US RIGHT NOW,
WE'RE ONLY A FEW DAYS FROM THIS
EVENT, AND WE WANT ANSWERS, WE
WANT RESOLUTION, YOU WANT
JUSTICE WHERE THERE REALLY ISN'T
JUSTICE TO BE HAD.
TALK TO US ABOUT THAT FEELING
AND WHAT WE SHOULD BE EXPECTING
IN THE SHORT TERM, MAYBE WHAT WE
SHOULD BE EXPECTING IN THE LONG
TERM AND HOW TO MAYBE NAVIGATE
SOME OF OUR EXPECTATIONS.
>> THAT'S A GREAT POINT.
AND LET ME JUST SAY THAT THIS
WAS A HORRIFICALLY-EMOTIONAL
EVENT.
AND SO WHAT WE'RE SEEING IS A
LOT OF EMOTIONAL RESPONSES.
PEOPLE SAYING, OH, WE SHOULD
TEAR DOWN THE SCHOOL OR, OH, WE
OUGHT TO LIMIT EVERYBODY'S GUN
RIGHTS ACROSS THE COUNTRY
INCLUDING ALL OF THE LAW-ABIDING
AMERICANS.
YOU KNOW, THESE ARE EMOTIONAL
RESPONSES, THEY'RE
UNDERSTANDABLE, BUT WHAT I WOULD
SAY TO PEOPLE IS WHAT WE NEED
HERE IF WE'RE GOING TO DO THE
BEST WE CAN AT SOLVING THESE
DIFFICULT PROBLEMS IS REASON.
AND EMOTION A LOT OF TIMES IS
THE ENEMY OF REASON.
SO I WOULD SAY THAT OVER THESE
HOLIDAYS SIT WITH THE EMOTION A
LITTLE BIT, LET THE EMOTION
PASS, AND THEN LET'S TRY TO
REALLY REASON THESE THINGS OUT
IN THE NEW YEAR.
JENNA: MAKES ME HEAR A LITTLE
CALM CANNER ALREADY HEARING
THAT, DR. RUSSELL, JUST TO SIT
WITH IT EVEN AS UNCOMFORTABLE IT
IS AND HOW MUCH WE GRIEVE FOR
THIS COMMUNITY AS WELL.
DR. RUSSELL, GREAT TO HAVE YOU
WITH US AGAIN, WE LOOK FORWARD
TO HAVING YOU BACK.
>> THANK YOU.
JON: SOME LATE-BREAKING NEWS ON
THE LOOMING FISCAL CLIFF.
WE ARE JUST GETTING WORD
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER ARE MEETING
AT THE WHITE HOUSE.
THIS AS NEW DETAILS ARE COMING
TO LIGHT ABOUT A POSSIBLE DEAL
WITH NEGOTIATORS REPORTEDLY
FINDING COMMON GROUND ON BOTH
SPENDING CUTS AND HIGHER TAXES
AS WELL.
CHIEF CONGRESSIONAL
CORRESPONDENT MIKE EMANUEL LIVE
ON CAPITOL HILL.
MIKE?
>> Reporter: WELL, JON, WE
UNDERSTAND THAT THAT WHITE HOUSE
MEETING BETWEEN PRESIDENT OBAMA
AND SPEAKER BOEHNER WRAPPED UP
JUST MOMENTS AGO.
IT LASTED 45 MINUTES, AND AIDES
ARE SAYING WE WILL NOT GET A
READOUT, BUT THERE CERTAINLY HAS
BEEN A FLURRY OF ACTIVITY ON THE
FISCAL CLIFF FRONT.
AIDES TO SPEAKER BOEHNER SAY IN
A FRIDAY PHONE CALL TO THE
PRESIDENT THE SPEAKER OFFERED TO
EXTEND THE BUSH TAX CUTS FOR
THOSE MAKING UP TO A MILLION
DOLLARS SO, THEREFORE, THOSE
ABOVE A MILLION DOLLARS WOULD
PAY SLIGHTLY HIGHER TAXES IN
EXCHANGE FOR SPENDING CUTS AND
ENTITLEMENT REFORM.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT THE
FRAMEWORK OF A POSSIBLE FISCAL
CLIFF DEAL.
IT INCLUDES $1 TRILLION IN CUTS,
$1 TRILLION IN NEW REVENUE.
THAT WOULD INCLUDE AN IMMEDIATE
DOWN PAYMENT AND THEN LAWMAKERS
WORKING OUT DETAILS IN THE NEW
YEAR.
POSSIBLY INCLUDING RAISING THE
NATION'S DEBT LIMIT, SOMETHING
THE WHITE HOUSE HAS BADLY
WANTED, EXTENDING UNEMPLOYMENT
INSURANCE, THE MEDICARE DOC FIX,
PAYROLL TAX CUT AND TAX
EXTENDERS.
ANY DEBT LIMIT INCREASE WOULD
REQUIRE CUTS B IN REFORMS OF AN
AMOUNT GREATER THAN THE
INCREASE, FOR THE SPEAKER
PUTTING MORE REVENUE IN THE FORM
OF HIGHER RATES ON THE TABLE ON
MILLIONAIRES WAS SEEN AS
SIGNIFICANT.
THE PRESIDENT HAS BEEN PUSHING
FOR UPPER INCOME AMERICANS TO
PAY HIGHER TAXES.
A LEADING HOUSE REPUBLICAN SAYS
HE HAS FAITH IN THE SPEAKER.
>> I TOLD JOHN BASED ON MY
KNOWLEDGE OF HIM AND HIS
COMMITMENT, I AM PREPARED TO
SUPPORT THE AGREEMENT THAT HE
ULTIMATELY NEGOTIATES CONVINCED
IT'S THE BEST WE CAN GET UNDER
THE CIRCUMSTANCE.
>> Reporter: SO ACTIVITY TO
TRY TO FIND COMMON GROUND AND
WORK OUT A FISCAL CLIFF DEAL HAS
CLEARLY PICKED UP.
THE PRESIDENT AND SPEAKER MET
THURSDAY LATE IN THE DAY AT THE
WHITE HOUSE, THEY HAD A FRIDAY
PHONE CALL AND NOW A MEETING
EARLIER TODAY JUST WRAPPING UP A
SHORT TIME AGO.
JON?
JON: MIKE EMANUEL AT THE CAPITOL
BUILDING FOR US RIGHT NOW, MIKE,
THANK YOU.
JENNA: CONTINUING COVERAGE OF
THE SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT INCLUDING A
DIFFERENT ANGLE FOR YOU, THE WAY
THAT YOU CAN HELP.
THERE'S CERTAINLY BEEN AN
OUTPOURING FROM AROUND THE
COUNTRY AND AROUND THE WORLD
FROM PEOPLE WHO WANT TO GET
INVOLVED AND HELP, AND WE HAVE A
GREAT LISTS OF RESOURCES SO YOU
CAN MAKE SURE YOUR DONATION GET
TOSS THE RIGHT PLACE.
>>> WE'D LIKE TO BRING YOU TO A
BREAKING NEWS STORY, DO WE HAVE
THAT OF GOVERNOR NIKKI HALEY?
THERE SHE IS.
SHALL WE LISTEN IN?
NIKKI HALEY IS ANNOUNCING THE
REPLACEMENT OF OUTGOING
REPUBLICAN SENATOR JIM DeMINT.
>> THE HERITAGE FOUNDATION IS
BLESSED.
HE WILL LIFT THEM UP TO AN
AMAZING NEW LEVEL.
IT'S A FOUNDATION I HAVE ALWAYS
HAD GREAT RESPECT FOR, AND THEY
COULD NOT HAVE MADE A MORE
PERFECT PICK.
IN THIS DECISION AND PROCESS
THAT WE WENT THROUGH, THERE IS
NO REPLACING JIM DeMINT.
THERE'S NO REPLACING HIM.
THERE'S NO ONE THAT CAN FILL HIS
SHOES, THERE'S NO ONE THAT CAN
REALLY CARRY ON THAT TORCH.
AND I DON'T, I THINK THAT SAYS A
LOT ABOUT HIM.
I THINK IT SAYS A LOT ABOUT HOW
HE HAS CHANGED THE FACE OF SOUTH
CAROLINA AND THE WAY THAT WE
HAVE A LOT TO BE PROUD OF.
BUT I ALSO THINK THAT THIS IS A
NEW DAY, AND IT IS, UM, WITH
GREAT PLEASURE THAT I AM
ANNOUNCING, UM, THAT I AM
APPOINTING OUR NEXT U.S. SENATOR
TO BE CONGRESSMAN TIM SCOTT.
[APPLAUSE]
MANY PEOPLE HAVE ASKED WHAT WENT
INTO THIS DECISION PROCESS, AND
IT WAS PRETTY SIMPLE.
HE UNDERSTANDS THE STRENGTH THAT
WE NEED TO HAVE IN OUR BUSINESS
COMMUNITY AS WE CONTINUE TO
FOCUS ON JOBS.
HE HAS SHOWN THAT WITH HIS
SUPPORT OF THE PORTS AND KNOWING
THAT THE DEEPENING NEEDS TO BE
THERE, HE'S SHOWN COURAGE WHEN
HE HELPED US WITH THE FIGHT
AGAINST NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS
BOARD AND THE UNIONS THAT TRIED
TO TAKE BOEING DOWN.
HE HAS SHOWN IT WITH HIS FISCAL
REPRESENTATION AND THE FACT THAT
HE KNOWS THE VALUE OF A DOLLAR.
HE UNDERSTANDS WHAT EVERY FAMILY
AND SMALL BUSINESS GOES THROUGH,
AND HE HAS STAYED CONSISTENT TO
THAT.
IT ALSO --
JENNA: SO THIS IS THE PROCESS IN
SOUTH CAROLINA.
THE GOVERNOR THERE ANNOUNCING
THE REPLACEMENT FOR SENATOR JIM
DeMINT AND ANNOUNCING THAT
CONGRESSMAN SCOTT IS TO BECOME
THE SENATOR FOR THAT STATE FOR
THE NEXT SEVERAL YEARS, I
BELIEVE UNTIL 2014, WHEN HE'LL
HAVE TO RUN FOR RE-ELECTION.
THAT WILL VACATE HIS SEAT IN THE
HOUSE.
BY THE WAY, THIS WILL BE THE
FIRST AFRICAN-AMERICAN GOP
SENATOR SINCE 1979, AND NIKKI
HALEY REFERRING IN SOME WAYS
THERE TO THE CHANGING OF THE
GUARD IN THE SOUTH CAROLINA
SENATE POSITION.
WE'LL BRING YOU BACK THERE IN
JUST A MOMENT, FOLLOW THAT
ANNOUNCEMENT DAVID DRUCKER'S
GOING TO BE WITH US IN JUST A
QUICK SECOND AFTER A BREAK TO
TALK ABOUT WHAT THIS MEANS FOR
CONGRESS AND THE PATH AHEAD IN
2013.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
EVEN RAGU USERS CHOSE PREGO.
PREGO?!
BUT I'VE BOUGHT RAGU FOR YEARS.
[ Thinking ] WONDER WHAT OTHER
QUESTIONABLE CHOICES I'VE MADE?
I CHOOSE DATE NUMBER 2!
WHOOO!
[ sigh of relief ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHOOSE TASTE. CHOOSE PREGO.
HI,
I'M Ensure Clear...
Clear, HUH?
I'M NOT JUICE OR FANCY WATER.
I'VE GOTINE GRAMS OF PROTEIN.
THAT'S THREE TIMES MORE THAN ME!
[ Female Announcer ]
Ensure Clear.
NINE GRAMS PROTEIN. ZERO FAT.
IN BLUEBERRY/POMEGRANATE
AND PEACH.
SHE ALSO LIKES
TO RIDE HER BIKE.
SHE KNOWS THE POTENTIAL
FOR MAKING OR LOSING MONEY
CAN POP UP ANYTIME.
THAT'S WHY SHE TRADES WITH
THE LEADER IN MOBILE TRADING.
SO SHE'S ALWAYS READY
TO TAKE ACTION,
NO MATTER HOW WILY...
OR WEIRD...
OR WONDERFULLY
THE MARKET'S BEHAVING...
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE WAY IT MOVES.
THE WAY IT CLEANS.
EVERYTHING ABOUT
THE ORAL-B POWER BRUSH
IS SIMPLY REVOLUTIONARY.
ORAL-B POWER BRUSHES OSCILLATE,
ROTATE
AND EVEN PULSATE
TO GENTLY LOOSEN AND BREAK UP
THAT STICKY PLAQUE
WITH MORE BRUSH MOVEMENTS
THAN MANUAL BRUSHES
AND EVEN
UP TO 50% MORE
THAN LEADING
SONIC TECHNOLOGY BRUSHES
FOR A SUPERIOR CLEAN.
ORAL-B POWER BRUSHES.
GO TO ORALB.COM
FOR THE LATEST OFFERS.
JON: YOU SAW IT LIVE HERE ON
FOX, SOUTH CAROLINA GOVERNOR
NIKKI HALEY JUST ANNOUNCING HER
CHOICE TO REPLACE REPUBLICAN
SENATOR JIM DeMINT.
SENATOR DeMINT ANNOUNCED TWO
WEEKS AGO HE WILL STEP TOWN
JANUARY 1ST.
REPUBLICAN CONGRESSMAN TIM SCOTT
WILL TAKE HIS PLACE, BECOMING
ONLY THE SIXTH AFRICAN-AMERICAN
TO HOLD A SEAT IN THE U.S.
SENATE AND THE FIRST
AFRICAN-AMERICAN GOP SENATOR
SINCE 1979.
LET'S TALK ABOUT THIS HISTORIC
MOVE WITH DAVID DRUCKER, AN
ASSOCIATE POLITICS EDITOR FOR
ROLL CALL.
JIM DeMINT BECAME POPULAR,
WELL KNOWN OUTSIDE OF SOUTH
CAROLINA AS A CONSERVATIVE
LEADER IN THE SENATE.
A LOT OF PEOPLE, A LOT OF
CONSERVATIVES DISAPPOINTED THAT
HE IS LEAVING THAT ROLE.
SO WHO IS THE MAN WHO'S
REPLACING HIM?
>> WELL, CONGRESSMAN TIM SCOTT
WAS ELECTED IN 2010.
HE'S ONE OF THE NEW SORT OF TEA
PARTY FRESHMEN, IF YOU WILL.
HE WAS IN LONGER GOING TO BE A
FRESHMAN COME THE NEXT CONGRESS,
AND I THINK THAT FOR
CONSERVATIVES WHO MONITOR VOTING
RECORDS, THEY'LL BE VERY
SATISFIED WITH TIM SCOTT.
I THINK HE'S A LITTLE BIT OF A
DIFFERENT, A TYPE OF POLITICIAN
THAN JIM DeMINT.
I THINK THAT SHE'S SHOWN A
LIT -- HE'S SHOWN A LITTLE BIT
MORE OF A PENCHANT TO I DON'T
WANT TO SAY BE AN ESTABLISHMENT
PLAYER, BUT HE DID HOLD AN
ELECTED LEADERSHIP POSITION IN
THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,
AND I THINK THAT HE'S A LITTLE
BITLESS OF AN OUTSIDER -- BIT
LESS OF AN OUTSIDER TYPE OF
POLITICIAN THAN HAS BEEN SENATOR
DeMINT.
JON: YEAH, THEY ARE BOTH TEA
PARTY FAVORITES.
THIS GUY, TIM SCOTT, HAS A
COMPELLING LIFE STORY; RAISED BY
A SINGLE MOTHER, HE AND HIS
SIBLINGS, AND SAID THAT HE WAS
IN DANGER OF DROPPING OUT OF
SCHOOL WHEN HE GOT A JOB AT A
CHICK
CHICK-FIL-A FRANCHISE, AND THE
MANAGER THERE SORT OF TOOK HIM
UNDER HIS WING.
>> YEAH, THAT'S CORRECT.
HE'S GOT A VERY COMPELLING
STORY.
IT'S NOT A BAD THING FOR THE
REPUBLICAN PARTY AT A TIME WHEN
IT'S DOING SOME SOUL SEARCHING
AND TRYING TO MAKE INROADS OR
LOOKING FOR HOW IT CAN MAKE
INROADS INTO ETHNIC MINORITY
VOTING POPULATIONS.
SO HAVING TIM SCOTT AS A SENATOR
AND ANY HUNDRED OF THESE GUYS
CAN MAKE NEWS ON ANY GIVEN DAY
JUST BECAUSE THEY'RE A SENATOR
IS GOING TO BE, COULD BE VERY
HELPFUL FOR THE REPUBLICAN
PARTY.
AND TIM SCOTT, I HAD INTERVIEWED
HIM IN THE PAST COUPLE OF
AND ONE OF THE THINGS HE TOLD ME
THAT I WAS STRUCK WITH IS THAT
IT EBB -- THE THINGS WERE A LOT
HARDER TO FIX THAN HE IMAGINED,
AND I THINK HE ENVISIONSES FOR
HIMSELF A VERY LONG POLITICAL
CAREER IN WASHINGTON D.C.
AND AS A SENATOR WHO SHOULD WIN
ELECTION IN 2014 TO SERVE OUT
THE REMAINDER OF SENATOR
DeMINT'S TERM, GIVEN THE TYPE
OF STATE HE COMES FROM AND HIS
POLITICS, HE COULD HAVE A VERY
LONG AND POSSIBLY BRIGHT FUTURE
AHEAD OF HIMSELF.
JON: RIGHT.
BECAUSE WE REMEMBER WHEN ROLAND
BURRIS TOOK PRESIDENT OBAMA'S
SENATE SEAT FOR TWO YEARS, THERE
WAS OF A LOT OF CONTROVERSY
ABOUT THAT AND, EVENTUALLY, HE
SAID, OKAY, I'LL JUST BE A PLACE
HOLDER, I'LL FILL THE SEAT UNTIL
THE ELECTION, AND THEN I'LL GET
OUT.
GOVERNOR HALEY SAID SHE WAS
LOOKING FOR A GUY WHO WANTS TO
KEEP THE SEAT, WANTS TO RUN
AGAIN.
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
GOVERNOR HALEY IS UP FOR
RE-ELECTION IN 2014, I THINK SHE
WAS LOOKING FOR SOMEBODY WHO
WOULD REFLECT WELL ON HER AND
SERVE HER WELL AS A, AS SOMEBODY
WHO IS JOINING HER AT THE TOP OF
THE TICKET ON THE 2014 BALLOT.
I ALSO THINK THAT FOR
CONSERVATIVES IN SOUTH CAROLINA
THIS IS AN APPOINTMENT THAT'S
GOING TO SATISFY THEM AND
REFLECT WELL ON HER.
SHE'S NOT NECESSARILY AT HOME AS
WELL LIKED AS SHE IS OUTSIDE
SOUTH CAROLINA, SO THIS
APPOINTMENT POLITICALLY WAS VERY
IMPORTANT FOR HER, AND I THINK
SHE DID WHAT SHE NEEDED TO DO,
AND I THINK TIM SCOTT SHOULD
MAKE A LOT OF PEOPLE HAPPY IN
SOUTH CAROLINA AT LEAST AT THIS
POINT.
HE COMES FROM CHARLESTON, HE'S
GOT STRONG TIES TO THE BUSINESS
COMMUNITY THERE, HE'S ALSO
STRONG WITH THE TEA PARTY
CONSERVATIVE CLASS.
AND SO I THINK IT WAS A VERY
POLITICALLY WELL-ROUNDED PICK,
AND HE'S LIKE BLG.
AND SO IF HE DOES HIS JOB, IF HE
TRANSITIONS WELL TO THE ROLE OF
SENATOR WHICH IS A BIT MORE
STATESMANLIKE THAN BEING JUST A
MEMBER OF THE HOUSE, THINGS
COULD GO QUITE WELL FOR HIM, AND
IT'LL REFLECT WELL ON GOVERNOR
HALEY.
JON: DAVID DRUCKER FROM "ROLL
CALL," THANK YOU.
>> ANYTIME, THANK YOU.
JON: TONIGHT GOVERNOR HALEY GOES
ON THE RECORD WITH GRETA TO TALK
ABOUT IN THIS POSITION TO
APPOINT SENATOR TIM SCOTT TO THE
SEAT.
THAT IS HERE AT 10 P.M. ON FOX
NEWS CHANNEL.
JENNA: WE'VE TALKED A LOT ABOUT
WHAT IT MEANS TO BECOME ENERGY
INDEPENDENT, BUT WHAT ABOUT THE
POTENTIAL BUSINESS OF SELLING
OUR ENERGY RESOURCES OVERSEAS?
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A CLOSER
LOOK AT THAT.
>>> ALSO, A NATION GRIEVING THIS
MORNING AS MANY AMERICANS ARE
ASKING WHAT CAN WE DO TO HELP
THE FAMILIES HOW OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
UP NEXT, WE'RE GOING TO TELL YOU
HOW YOU CAN MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
♪
MY DOCTOR TOLD ME CALCIUM
IS EFFICIENTLY ABSORBED IN SMALL
CONTINUOUS AMOUNTS.
Citracal Slow Release
CONTINUOUSLY RELEASES CALCIUM
PLUS D
WITH EFFICIENT ABSORPTION
IN ONE DAILY DOSE.
Citracal Slow Release.
Progresso.
In what world do potatoes,
bacon and cheese
add up to 100 calories?
Your world.
♪
[ whispers ]
Real bacon...
Creamy cheese...
100 calories...
[ Chef ] Ma'am
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
JON: RIGHT NOW THE NATION IN
MOURNING AS MANY AMERICANS SEND
THEIR PRAYERS TO THE NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, COMMUNITY, MANY OF
THEM WONDERING HOW THEY CAN HELP
GRIEVING FAMILIES.
HEATHER IS AT OUR BREAKING NEWS
DESK, SHE HAS SOME INFORMATION.
>> Reporter: HI, JON.
SO MANY OF OUR VIEWERS HAVE
ASKED HOW THEY CAN HELP THE
FAMILIES AFFECTED BY THE
SHOOTING, SO WE'VE TAKEN A LACK
ATOM OF THE -- A LOOK AT SOME OF
THE GROUPS.
FIRST, THE UNITED WAY OF
CONNECTICUT ESTABLISHED THE
SANDY HOOK SUPPORT FUND.
THIS GROUP WILL PROVIDE SUPPORT
SERVICES TO FAMILIES AND TO THE
COMMUNITY.
THEY SAY THAT ALL DONATIONS FROM
THIS FUND WILL GO DIRECTLY TO
THOSE FAMILIES THAT HAVE BEEN
AFFECTED.
THE AMERICAN RED CROSS IS ALSO
SETTING UP A FAMILY CENTER IN
THAT AREA, THEY'LL PROVIDE
INITIAL GRIEF COMING WHICH IS
SOMETHING, OF COURSE, THE RED
CROSS DID AFTER THE NEP ATTACKS
AND OTHER TRAGEDIES.
THEY HAVE NOT SET UP A SPECIFIC
SANDY FUND, SO DOE NAWTION --
DONATIONS WILL GO TO THE GROUP'S
GENERAL FUND X. ALSO THE NEWTOWN
FAMILY EMERGENCY SERVICES IS
MAKING COUNSELING AVAILABLE,
THEY'RE ALSO ACCEPTING DONATIONS
THAT WILL GO DIRECTLY TO
VICTIMS' FAMILIES.
AS FAMILIES BEGIN TO HOLD
FUNERAL SERVICES, THE NEWTOWN
MEMORIAL FUND IS HELPING TO PAY
THOSE EXPENSES.
THAT GROUP WILL WORK WITH THE
TOWN EVENTUALLY TO HELP DESIGN
AND BUILD A MEMORIAL TO THE
VICTIMS.
NOW FINALLY, THERE'S A MEMORIAL
FUND THAT'S BEING SET UP FOR THE
FAMILY OF THIS LITTLE GIRL,
EMILY PARKER.
SHE DIED IN THE SHOOTING.
FRIENDS OF THE FAMILY SAY THAT
THAT FAMILY WILL NEED HELP WITH
EXPENSES THAT THEY HADN'T
PREVIOUSLY PLANNED FOR.
THE FATHER OF THAT LITTLE GIRL,
ROBBIE PARKER, SPOKE ABOUT HIS
DAUGHTER OVER THE WEEKEND, AND
GET THIS, JON, HE EXTENDED
PRAYERS TO THE FAMILY OF THE MAN
WHO TOOK HIS LITTLE GIRL'S LIFE.
HE SAID THIS, QUOTE: IT'S A
HORRIFIC TRAGEDY, AND WE WANT
EVERYBODY TO KNOW THAT OUR
HEARTS AND PRAYERS GO OUT TO
THEM, AND CAN THAT INCLUDES THE
SHOOTER'S FAMILY.
OTHER CHARITIES ARE BEING SET
UP, AND WE WILL KEEP YOU POSTED
ON ALL THAT INFORMATION, IN THE
MEANTIME GO, TO FOXNEWS.COM FOR
ALL THE LATEST INFORMATION.
JON: YEAH.
SOME VERY GOOD INFORMATION
THERE.
HEATHER, THANK YOU.
♪
JENNA: WELL, SOME NEW
DEVELOPMENTS IN THE NATIONAL
DEBATE OVER CLEAN ENERGY TODAY.
THE ENERGY DEPARTMENT IS WORKING
ON A NEW PROPOSAL THEY SAY THAT
WILL MAXIMIZE PROFITS BY
EXPORTING NATURAL GAS OVERSEAS.
JOHN ROBERTS IS LIVE IN ATLANTA
WITH THE DETAILS ON THIS.
HI, JOHN.
>> Reporter: HEY, JENNA, GOOD
AFTERNOON TO YOU.
WE'VE TALKED ABOUT THE SO-CALLED
SHALE GAS REVOLUTION, FRACKING.
IT HAS CREATED SO MUCH ABUNDANT
NATURAL GAS THAT PRICES HAVE
CRASHED THROUGH FLOOR, AND NOW
THE INDUSTRY IS LOOKING TO LINE
ITS POCKETS WITH A LITTLE MORE
CASH BY EXPORTING IT.
IN FACT, THE U.S. FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT HAS GOT 15
APPLICATIONS TO BUILD HUGE
TERMINALS TO EXPORT THAT GAS TO
NONFREE TRADE AGREEMENT
COUNTRIES, AND ALL THIS HAS
CREATED SOME INTERESTING BED
FELLOWS, FIRST OF ALL OF, THE
WHITE HOUSE ON THE SAME PAGE AS
THE INDUSTRY AFTER A REPORT SAID
EXPORTING NATURAL GAS WOULD BE
GOOD FOR THE ECONOMY.
WE HAVE PEOPLE LIKE SENATOR RON
WYDEN, CONGRESSMAN ED MARKEY OF
MASSACHUSETTS ALL LINING UP IN
OPPOSITION ALONG WITH THE DOW
CHEMICAL CORPORATION.
THESE THREE ARGUING THAT EXPORTS
COULD RAISE THE PRICE OF NATURAL
GAS DOMESTICALLY AND HURT
INDUSTRIES LIKE DOW THAT USE AN
AWFUL LOT OF IT.
HERE'S WHAT THE CEO SAID ABOUT
THAT.
HE SAID, QUOTE: THE REPORT, THE
DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY REPORT,
OFFERS THE BAF LING CONCLUSION
THAT THE U.S. WOULD BE BETTER
OFF USING ITS DOMESTIC NATURAL
GAS ADVANTAGE TO FUEL GROWTH AND
JOBS IN OTHER REGIONS VERSUS
STRENGTHENING THE U.S. ECONOMY
ASK THROUGH MANUFACTURING AND
BENEFITING CONSUMERS WITH LOWER
ENERGY COSTS.
THAT BROUGHT THIS REACTION FROM
THE OIL AND GAS INDUSTRY.
>> WHAT'S GOOSE IS GOOD FOR THE
GANDER.
IF THE CHEMICAL INDUSTRY WANTS
THE FREE MARKET TO WORK SO THEY
CAN PRODUCE PRODUCT AND EXPORT
IT, WE SHOULD APPLY THE SAME
STANDARD TO THE NATURAL GAS AND
OIL INDUSTRY.
>> Reporter: SO HOW MUCH
NATURAL GAS DO WE ACTUALLY HAVE?
WELL, ACCORDING TO THE INDUSTRY,
ABOUT 900 YEARS -- 100 YEARS'
WORTH, SO MUCH SO THAT IN THE
U.S. COULD BECOME ENERGY
SELF-SUFFICIENT WITHIN THE NEXT
FEW YEARS.
THE CURRENT PRICE OF MATCH ALGAS
IS ABOUT $3.43 PER MILLION BTU.
ACCORDING TO THE DEPARTMENT OF
ENERGY REPORT, EXPORTING NATURAL
GAS COULD RAISE THAT PRICE BY
MORE THAN A DOLLAR OVER THE NEXT
FIVE YEARS WHICH, JENNA,
INDUSTRY SAYS IT JUST DOESN'T
WANT TO SEE HAPPEN.
JENNA: ALL RIGHT.
WE'LL CONTINUE TO WATCH THAT
STORY, JOHN.
THANK YOU.
JON: ANOTHER POLITICAL BATTLE
SHAPING UP ON CAPITOL HILL RIGHT
NOW OVER EMERGENCY FUNDS MEANT
TO HELP IN THE RECOVERY EFFORT
AFTER SUPERSTORM SANDY.
WHY SOME LAWMAKERS ARE CALLING
THE $60 BILLION PRICE TAG
ABSURDLY HIGH.
>>> AND IT SEEMS EVERY DAY WE'RE
GETTING REPORTS OF ESCALATING
VIOLENCE IN SYRIA, BUT IT'S
OFTEN DIFFICULT TO GET FIRSTHAND
INFORMATION.
STRAIGHT AHEAD, WE'LL TALK WITH
A FREELANCE JOURNALIST WHO JUST
RETURNED FROM THE WAR ZONE.
JENNA: WELCOME BACK,
EVERYONE.
WE'RE AWAITING A FEW LIVE
EVENTS WE TO TELL YOU ABOUT.
AT THE LEFT OF YOUR SCREEN
IS NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE AWAITING ANOTHER
STATEMENT FROM LIEUTENANT
PAUL VANCE WHO HAS BEEN
BRIEFING THE PRESS EVERY FEW
HOURS ABOUT THE LATEST IN
THE INVESTIGATION ON THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
AND THE MURDERS THERE THAT
HAPPENED ON FRIDAY.
WE'LL BRING YOU THERE WHEN
HE STEPS TO THE MICROPHONE.
ON THE RIGHT OF YOUR SCREEN
IS THE PRESS BRIEFING ROOM
IN THE WHITE HOUSE.
WE EXPECT JAY CARNEY TO STEP
TO THE PODIUM.
AT ANY MOMENT WE EXPECT TO
GET LATEST NEWS FROM HIM ON
THE FISCAL CLIFF
NEGOTIATIONS, MEETING
BETWEEN THE PRESIDENT AND
JOHN BAIN ARE AND AS WELL AS
ANY STATEMENTS TO WHAT
TRANSPIRED IN KECK CUT.
WE'LL BRING YOU TO EITHER
LOCATION LIVE WHEN WE SEE
ANYONE STEP TO THE PODIUM
AND TO BRING YOU THE NEWS.
>>> WE TURN TO CAPITOL HILL
NOW.
ANOTHER BIG WEEK THAT
HAPPENED OVER LAST FEW WEEKS
IS SUPERSTORM SANDY.
THERE IS NEW QUESTIONS ABOUT
THE $60 BILLION SPENDING
BILL AIMED AT HELPING
COMMUNITIES DEVASTATED BY
THE STORM.
SOME LAWMAKERS ARE SLAMMING
PET PROJECTS TACKED ONTO THE
BILL, THEY CALL IT, THOSE
PET PROJECTS SAYING THEY
HAVE LITTLE TO DO WITH THE
STORM AND DON'T LIKE THE
PRICE TAG.
DOUG McKELWAY IS LIVE IN
WASHINGTON WITH MORE ON
THIS.
DOUG WHAT IS THIS ALL ABOUT?
>> Reporter: THE SENATE IS
EXPECTED TO TAKE UP THE
SUPPLEMENTAL SPENDING BILL
AT 2:00 P.M. AND WE EXPECT
TO HEAR SOME REPUBLICAN
OPPOSITION AS YOU SAID.
WITH DEMOCRATS IN CONTROL
AND NATURE OF THE HARDSHIP
IN NEW YORK AND NEW JERSEY
AND PRESSURE PUT ON LAWMAKER
BY HOME STATE GOVERNORS
THERE IS LITTLE DOUBT OF ITS
PASSAGE.
>> THIS IS A TREMENDOUS NEED
FOR THE STATE.
WE SPOKE ABOUT THE SCALE OF
THE DAMAGE.
WHICH IS JUST DEVASTATING.
PEOPLE ARE STILL REELING
FROM THIS TRAUMA.
AND NEW YORK NEEDS HELP AND
NEW YORK HAS BEEN THERE FOR
OTHER PARTS OF THE COUNTRY
WHEN THEY HAVE NEEDED HELP
AND THAT'S WHAT WE'RE ASKING
FOR THE SAME TODAY.
>> Reporter: IT'S A
DIFFERENT STORY IN THE HOUSE
WHERE REPUBLICANS INDICATED
THAT FEMA HAS ENOUGH MONEY
IN RESERVES TO LAST THROUGH
THE SPRINGTIME.
ALSO IN THE HOUSE
REPUBLICANS CONCERNED WITH
OUT OF CONTROL SPENDING
ASKED ANY SUPPLEMENTAL
SPENDING BILL FOR HURRICANE
SANDY REPAIR OFFSET WITH
SPENDING CUTS THAT DRAWN THE
IRE OF DEMOCRATIC LAWMAKERS
IN BOTH HOUSES.
>> WE TALKED A LITTLE BIT
ABOUT THE POLITICAL
DIFFICULTIES OF GETTING THIS
DONE.
WE KNOW IT IS NOT GOING TO
BE EASY.
>> Reporter: CRITICS OF THE
$60 BILLION PRICE TAG SAY
THAT PRESIDENT OBAMA
SPENDING REQUEST IS ANOTHER
CASE OF THROWING MONEY
WILLY-NILLY AT A PROBLEM
WITHOUT PROPER ACCOUNTING.
MATT MAYOR OF THE HERITAGE
FOUNDATION WROTE HE WILL
EXPLOIT LOOPHOLES IN THE
BUDGET CONTROL ACT THAT
ALLOW THIS NEW SPENDING
ABOVE EXISTING LIMITS.
IN AN ERA OF CHRONIC
TRILLION DOLLAR DEFICITS
THIS IS AN ACT OF WILLFUL
FENCE.
THEY WILL NEED SEVEN
REPUBLICAN VOTES IN THE
SENATE TO MOVE THIS.
IT IS UNCLEAR HOW THEY WILL
RECONCILE THE DIFFERENCE.
JENNA: DOUG, KEEP US
UPDATED.
JON: WE'LL TAKE YOU OVERSEAS
TO THE CIVIL WAR IN SYRIA
RAGES ON IN THE CAPITAL
DAMASCUS AFTER A GOVERNMENT
AIRSTRIKE HITS THE LARGEST
PALESTINIAN REFUGEE CAMP
THERE.
THE ATTACK KILLING AT LEAST
EIGHT PEOPLE, SPARKING A
MASSIVE NEW EXODUS OF
REFUGEES.
LELAND VITTERT LIVE FROM OUR
MIDDLE EAST BUREAU IN
JERUSALEM.
LELAND?
>> Reporter: JON, THE SYRIAN
GOVERNMENT CLAIMS THAT
REFUGEE CAMP WAS USED BY THE
OPPOSITION AND REBELS TO
STAGE ATTACKS FROM.
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE SEEING
INSIDE OF SYRIA RIGHT NOW.
THIS IS INSURGENCY CIVIL
WAR.
THE REBELS ARE AMONG THE
PEOPLE.
THAT'S WHY YOU'RE HAVING
THESE LARGE-SCALE ARTILLERY
ATTACKS AND AIR ATTACKS ON
CIVILIAN POPULATION.
THE RESULTS OF THOSE COULD
BE CATASTROPHIC.
AND CAUSED A NUMBER OF
CASUALTIES IN THE REFUGEE
CAMP AND OTHER PLACES
CREATING THIS EXODUS OF
SYRIAN CIVILIANS.
THE DEATH TOLL IN SYRIA WELL
ABOVE 40,000.
OVER A MILLION PEOPLE ARE
DISPLACED.
HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS HAVE
FLED OUTSIDE OF THEIR
COUNTRY BUT IT COMES AT AN
INTERESTING TIME HERE AS THE
SYRIAN REBELS ARE BEGINNING
TO GAIN WHAT APPEARS TO BE A
LITTLE BIT OF THE UPPER HAND
IN THIS BATTLE.
THE NOOSE IS TIGHTENING
AROUND DAMASCUS.
THE FIGHTING IS MOVING FROM
THE OUTLYING COUNTRY AREAS
IN TOWARDS THE CAPITAL AND
IN TOWARDS THE LARGER
CITIES.
THE REBELS ARE BRINGING THE
FIGHT TO THE GOVERNMENT
RATHER THAN THE GOVERNMENT
BEING ABLE TO GO AFTER THE
REBELS.
THE REBELS ARE BECOMING
INCREASINGLY BETTER ARMED.
VIDEO OUT OF SYRIA CERTAINLY
SHOWS THAT.
THEIR ATTACKS ARE BETTER
COORDINATED.
THEIR ATTACKS ARE MORE
SUCCESSFUL.
THAT MAY BE ONE OF THE
REASONS THE SYRIAN VICE
PRESIDENT JUST SAID IN THE
PAST COUPLE DAYS HE DOESN'T
THINK THEY CAN ACTUALLY BEAT
THE SYRIAN REBELS AS THE
GOVERNMENT.
THAT MAY BE THE FIRST SIGN
THE SYRIAN REGIME IS WILLING
TO NEGOTIATE.
JON?
JON: THAT WOULD BE AMAZING.
LELAND VITTERT REPORTING
LIVE.
THANK YOU.
JENNA: NORMALLY WHEN WE TALK
ABOUT SYRIA WE HAVE TO OFFER
A DISCLAIMER TO BE
RESPONSIBLE JUNENALISTS WHEN
WE SHOW VIDEO FROM SYRIA IT
IS AMATEUR VIDEO AND DON'T
HAVE A CLEAR SOURCE.
WE TODAY DO.
WE HAVE VIDEO FROM A
FREELANCE JOURNALIST,
CHRISTIE WILCOX, WHO SPENT
THREE MONTHS TRAVELING
THROUGH SYRIA TO GET A LOOK
AT THE CIVIL WAR.
SHE RECENTLY RETURNED TO THE
UNITED STATES AND JOINS US
LIVE FROM LOS ANGELES.
CHRISTIE, TELL US WHEN AND
HOW YOU DECIDED TO TRAVEL TO
SYRIA?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, IT WAS A
LONG PROCESS, A LONG
DECISION IN THE MAKING.
SEVERAL OTHER PEOPLE, I'M A
BIG FAN OF TRAVELING
INTERNATIONALLY AND
UNFORTUNATELY THERE'S A LOT
OF CHAOS GOING ON IN SYRIA
RIGHT NOW AND I BELIEVED
THAT THEIR STORY NEEDED TO
BE TOLD.
SO THAT WAS A MAIN REASON
FOR ME GOING OVERCEASE.
JENNA: LELAND MENTIONED AN
ATTACK ON A REFUGEE CAMP.
YOU SPENT TIME VIDEOTAPING
REFUGEES IN THE AREA.
WE HAVE SOME OF VIDEO.
CAN YOU TELL US A LITTLE BIT
ABOUT THAT?
>> YEAH.
I SPENT A LOT OF TIME IN THE
REFUGEE CAMP JUST OVER THE
SYRIAN BORDER.
WHEN I WAS THERE IN AUGUST
THERE WAS REALLY NOTHING
THERE.
IN THE MOST RECENT MONTHS,
YOU'RE SEEING THOUSANDS OF
REFUGEES, INTERNALLY
DISPLACED PEOPLE COMING FROM
INSIDE SYRIA OUT TO THESE
REFUGEE CAMPS BECAUSE THEY
DON'T HAVE ELECTRICITY.
THEY DON'T HAVE FOOD.
THEY DON'T HAVE WATER.
SO THEY'RE TRYING TO GET
FED.
THEY'RE TRYING TO FIND
SAFETY.
SOME OF THE ISSUES THAT
YOU'RE GOING TO SEE IN THE
REFUGEE CAMP, ESPECIALLY
LOOKING AT THE BOMBARDMENTS
IS, YOU KNOW, THE, WITH THE
NO-FLY ZONE NOT BEING
ACCESSIBLE THERE, THEY'RE
GOING AND THEY'RE BOMBING
SOME OF THESE TENTS.
SO WHEN YOU HAVE THOUSANDS
OF PEOPLE COMING INTO THE
REFUGEE CAMP WITH NO PLACE
TO STAY, THEY'RE FORCED TO
GO BACK INTO THE POPULATION
AS WELL.
JENNA: ONE OF THE OTHER
VIDEO ITEMS THAT WE HAVE,
VIDEO CLIPS THAT YOU SHOT
BRINGS US OUTSIDE OF ALEPPO.
THAT IS A CITY WE TALKED A
LOT ABOUT AND THE BACK AND
FORTH WITH REBEL FORCES
THERE, WHO WE CALL THE REBEL
FORCES, AS WELL AS THE
GOVERNMENT.
TELL US A LITTLE BIT ABOUT
YOUR EXPERIENCE THERE AND
WHAT YOUR SENSE IS OF THE
QUOTE, UNQUOTE REBELS THAT
ARE FIGHTING THIS WAR?
>> WELL IT WAS A REALLY
INTERESTING COMMUNITY.
THE COMMUNITY IS ALBAB.
IT SITS RIGHT OUTSIDE OF
ALEPPO.
WHEN IT WAS LIBERATED IT WAS
AROUND THE BEGINNING OF THE
RAMADAN.
THEY BOMBED A HOSPITAL KNOWN
FOR KID ANY TRANSPLANTS THAT
SITS UP ON THE HILL.
WHAT THEY'RE TRYING TO DO IS
CREATE A LITTLE NORMALCY OUT
OF LIVING AN ABNORMAL LIFE.
THE VIDEO YOU'RE SEEING HERE
IS THE HOSPITAL THAT HAS
BEEN BOMBED.
WHAT THEY DID, THEY TOOK THE
PEOPLE IN THIS HOSPITAL AND
CREATED KIND OF A MAKESHIFT
AREA INSIDE SOME OF THE
MOSQUES WHERE THEY WOULD
TAKE, YOU KNOW, THE
OPPOSITION FIGHTERS.
THEY WOULD TAKE CIVILIANS
WHO HAVE BEEN INJURED AND
THEY WOULD PUT THEM IN THERE
AND, YOU KNOW, AT TIMES
HOPEFULLY THEY HAVE ENOUGH
MEDICAL STAFF, ENOUGH
TREATMENT FACILITIES INSIDE
THESE, THESE FACILITIES,
MAKESHIFT FACILITIES THAT
THEY HAVE ACTUALLY
DEVELOPED.
JENNA: WE'RE SHOWING SOME OF
THAT FOOTAGE AS WELL.
FINAL VIDEO YOU BROUGHT US,
AGAIN WE'RE SO GRATEFUL TO
GET SOME OF YOUR INSIGHTS ON
THIS.
JUST ON FRIDAY WE LEARNED
THERE WAS A DECISION MADE
SOME NATO TROOPS INCLUDING
AMERICAN TROOPS WILL BE SENT
TO THE BORDER BETWEEN TURKEY
AND SYRIA AS WELL AS PATRIOT
MISSILES.
THAT IS WHERE YOU SPENT A
LOT OF YOUR TIME.
TELL US ABOUT THE BORDER.
HOW VULNERABLE IS IT?
WHAT WILL THESE TROOPS
CONFRONT?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, AT THIS
POINT I THINK IT'S JUST THE
RIGHT THING FOR THE AMERICAN
GOVERNMENT TO DO.
I MEAN WE'VE SEEN SO MUCH
BOMBARDMENT.
WHEN I WAS ON THE BORDER,
THIS VIDEO YOU'RE SEEING IS
WHERE THE ORIGINAL SPILLOVER
WAS STARTING TO TAKE PLACE.
THIS IN THE PLACE WHERE THE
REBELS ARE GEARING UP TO
FIGHT AGAINST THE SYRIAN
GOVERNMENT AND THE PEOPLE
WERE REALLY SCARED, YOU KNOW,
THE TOWN IN WHERE THE
SPILLOVER WAS HAPPENING, THE
SYRIAN GOVERNMENT WAS
HITTING THEM VERY, VERY HARD
AND IT WAS LEAKING OVER TO
THE TOWN NEXT TO IT IN
TURKEY.
SO, YOU KNOW, IT IS ONLY
RIGHT FOR THEM TO BE ABLE TO
DEFEND THEMSELVES.
I MEAN, I THINK THE ONE
THING THAT TURKEY DID REALLY
WELL WAS THEY STEPPED UP
RIGHT OFF THE BAT AND THEY
SAID, THIS IS WHAT IS
ACCEPTABLE AND THIS IS WHAT
IS NOT ACCEPTABLE, WHICH IS
THE REASON WHY THE REGIME
BACKED OFF FROM THE GET-GO.
THAT'S WHAT WE NEED TO
CONTINUE TO DO IS TO SUPPORT
OUR ALLIES.
JENNA: VERY INTERESTING
PERSPECTIVE FOR US TODAY,
CHRISTIE.
THANKS SO MUCH FOR JOINING
US AND SHARE YOUR VIDEO.
WE LOOK FORWARD TO HAVING
YOU BACK.
APPRECIATE IT VERY MUCH.
>> THANKS, JENNA, LET'S HOPE
THEY GET THAT WAR OVER WITH
SOON.
AN OVERSEAS COMPANY FACES
AMERICAN JUSTICE, FOUND
LIABLE FOR CAUSING POLLUTION
IN THE UNITED STATES.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT THE
RAMIFICATIONS AND SHOW YOU
WHERE THIS IS HAPPENING.
>> STILL AHEAD THE
INVESTIGATION INTO THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTINGS
PICKING UP SPEED AS WE LEARN
NEW DETAILS ABOUT THE GUNMAN
AND HIS FAMILY LIFE.
JENNA: OUT TO NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AND THE LATEST
PRESS BRIEFING.
LET'S GO AHEAD AND LISTEN
IN.
>> WE'LL MAINTAIN SECURITY
OF THAT FACILITY
INDEFINITELY.
IN DOING SO WE'RE GOING TO,
AT THIS TIME, ALLOW THE
SCHOOL SYSTEM TO MOVE THE
FURNITURE TO THE NEXT
LOCATION, THE BUILDING THAT
IS GOING TO BE UTILIZED TO
CONTINUE THE EDUCATION OF
THE CHILDREN, K-4.
THAT INFORMATION WILL COME
FROM THE BOARD OF EDUCATION
AND THE SCHOOL
SUPERINTENDENT AS
APPROPRIATE ON THEIR WEBSITE.
WE ARE STILL GUARDING AND
WE'LL STILL CONTINUE TO
GUARD BOTH SCENES AS CRIME
SCENES AS WE'VE INDICATED
THIS MORNING.
AGAIN, THAT WILL, THAT WILL
GO ON INDEFINITELY.
REGARDING FUNERAL SERVICES,
AS YOU KNOW THEY'RE BEING
PLANNED AND PUBLICIZED BY
THE FAMILIES AT FUNERAL
HOMES.
A COUPLE THINGS WE WANT TO
RESTATE.
EACH FAMILY HAS LIAISON
TROOPER THAT WILL MAINTAIN
CONTACT AND BE WITH THEM.
IN ADDITION NEWTOWN AND
STATE POLICE AND SURROUNDING
POLICE DEPARTMENTS ARE
PLANNING ASSISTANCE TO EACH
FUNERAL SERVICE, SO IT GOES
UNSCATHED.
I HAVE TO ASK AND PLEAD,
LITERALLY THE WORD IS PLEAD,
FAMILIES ARE GRIEVING.
MANY OF THE FAMILIES HAVE
ASKED THAT TO PLEASE AFFORD
THEM THEIR PRIVACY AS THEY
GO THROUGH THIS TERRIBLE,
TERRIBLE TRAGEDY THAT
THEY'RE DEALING WITH.
I'VE BEEN ASKED, THE
LIEUTENANT WITH ME, HAS BEEN
ASKED TO PASS THAT ON TO YOU
AS CLEARLY AND CONCISELY AS
POSSIBLE.
THAT IS THE BEST WAY I CAN
DO IT.
>> AT THIS TIME I CAN TAKE A
COUPLE OF QUESTIONS.
WE'LL SEE IF WE CAN CLEAR UP
ANYTHING.
THEN I'M GOING TO SPEAK A
LITTLE BIT ABOUT OUR FUTURE
GET-TOGETHERS.
>> [INAUDIBLE].
>> CORRECT.
GOING TO ASK ME A HARD
QUESTION AND I'M TRYING TO
RECALL.
THERE WERE TWO PHONE CALLS.
THE QUESTION WAS, ABOUT THE,
THERE WERE TWO THREATS OF
VIOLENCE.
WE CAN SIMPLY SAY THEY CAME
IN TWO SEPARATE PHONE CALLS
AGAINST THE SAME FACILITY
WHICH WAS THE CHURCH, THE
CATHOLIC CHURCH IN TOWN.
TWO TELEPHONE CALLS
RECEIVED.
AGAIN, AS I STATED BEFORE,
THOSE ARE CRIMINAL ACTS.
THOSE ARE ACTS BEING
THOROUGHLY AND COMPLETELY
INVESTIGATED AND FOLLOW-UP
WILL BE DONE BY EITHER STATE
AND OR FEDERAL AUTHORITIES
RELATIVE TO ANY THREATS OF
THAT NATURE THAT SOMEONE SET
FORTH.
THOSE ARE THE, WHAT I MEANT
BY THE THREATS, OKAY?
NEXT PLEASE.
>> HOW MUCH TRAINING DO YOU
THINK THE SUSPECT HAD?
ARE YOU AWARE OR ANY
INDICATION OR WHERE HE WAS
PRACTICING?
>> CERTAINLY, I CAN'T EVEN
BEGIN TO SPECULATE.
WE SIMPLY DON'T HAVE THAT
INFORMATION TO PROVIDE TO
YOU.
AS I STATED NUMEROUS TIMES,
WE DEFINITELY, WE DEFINITELY
ARE PEELING THAT ONION BACK
LAYER BY LAYER.
WE'LL KNOW ALL THAT
INFORMATION, BELIEVE ME WHEN
I TELL YOU THERE IS A TEAM
WORKING ON JUST THAT,
WORKING WITH ATF AND OTHER
FEDERAL AUTHORITIES, STATE
AUTHORITIES AND LOCAL
AUTHORITIES, TO MAKE SURE
THAT NO STONE IS LEFT
UNTURNED REGARDING THAT
SPECIFIC TRAINING, SIR.
>> -- REMOVE THE HARD DRIVE
OF THE COMPUTER?
THAT IS MAKING IT DIFFICULT
TO RECOVER ANYTHING?
>> SIR, I DIDN'T INDICATE
WHAT EVIDENCE WAS, HAS BEEN
SEIZED AT ANY LOCATION.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE THAT
INFORMATION CAME FROM BUT WE
DID SEIZE SIGNIFICANT
EVIDENCE AT THE RESIDENCE.
WE ARE ANALYZING AND WILL
ANALYZE.
IT IS A VERY PAINSTAKING
PROCESS IN FORENSIC SCIENCE.
IT WILL TAKE SOME TIME TO DO
THAT.
>> WAS THE HARD DRIVE
REMOVED?
>> WE DON'T DISCUSS
EVIDENCE, SIR.
I'M SORRY.
WE DON'T DISCUSS EVIDENCE OR
ITS CONTENT AND WHAT IT IS.
>> CLARIFY A COUPLE THINGS.
>> YES, SIR.
>> EARLIER TWO PEOPLE WERE
SHOT AND SURVIVED.
>> THAT'S CORRECT, SIR.
>> DO YOU KNOW WHERE, WHAT
LOCATION AT THE SCHOOLS?
>> I CAN'T.
THERE WERE TWO PEOPLE THAT
WERE WOUND.
AND DID SURVIVE, TWO ADULTS,
THAT IS CORRECT.
THEY WERE WOUNDED IN THE
LOWER EXTREMITIES.
I DO NOT KNOW THE LOCATION
IN THE SCHOOL.
I CAN NOT ANSWER THAT
QUESTION.
>> BOTH WOMAN?
>> DO YOU KNOW HOW MANY
STUDENTS WERE IN EACH
CLASSROOM, HOW MANY
SURVIVORS WERE IN EACH
CLASSROOM?
>> NO.
>> NO, I'M SORRY, I DON'T.
HE IS ASKING ABOUT DO WE
HAVE SPECIFIC LOCATION OF
SURVIVORS AND LOCATION OF
STUDENTS AND FACULTY AND
STAFF AND I DON'T HAVE THAT,
I'M SORRY.
YES, MA'AM?
>> CAN YOU IDENTIFY THE
ADULTS YET.
>> NO, WE HAVE NOT YET.
THEY ARE CONSIDERED
WITNESSES AND WE DO NOT
IDENTIFY WITNESSES.
YES, MA'AM.
>> INDICATES SOME OF THAT
ELECTRONIC EVIDENCE WAS
DESTROYED OR UNAVAILABLE.
WILL YOU BE WORKING WITH
INTERNET COMPANIES LIKE --
[INAUDIBLE]
>> GOOD QUESTIONS AND GOOD
WAY TO ASK IT.
I CAN ONLY TELL YOU WE
SEIZED EVIDENCE.
IF, IF THERE IS COMPUTER
EVIDENCE AND I STRONGLY SAY
THAT IF, WE DO HAVE A
COMPUTER CRIMES TEAM AT OUR
STATE FORENSIC LABORATORY
THAT ARE EXPERTS RETRIEVING
ANY TYPE OF ELECTRONIC
EVIDENCE AND DATA.
I WILL LEAVE THAT THERE,
PLEASE.
>> -- SCHOOLS LOCKED DOWN
EARLIER TODAY?
>> THOSE ARE HANDLED BY
LOCAL AUTHORITIES.
TWO LOCKDOWNS IN SURROUNDING
COMMUNITIES HAVE BEEN
CLEARED.
YES?
>> CAN YOU TELL US ALLEGED
RIFLE BUSHMASTER RIFLE --
[INAUDIBLE]
>> I CAN NOT TELL YOU THAT
BECAUSE I DO NOT KNOW.
AS I SAID, THIS MORNING,
THAT WEAPON, FROM THE DAY IT
WAS BUILT TO THE DAY WE
SEIZED IT, WE'LL LOOK AT
EVERY ASPECT OF IT FROM STEM
TO STERN, WHERE IT'S BEEN,
WHO'S HAD IT AND ALL THE
CLIPS, THE AMMUNITION,
EVERYTHING TO DO WITH ALL
THE AMMUNITION.
>> JUST FOLLOW UP TO THAT.
A LOT OF PEOPLE WATCHING AT
HOME SAY, THERE IS NO
MYSTERY HERE ANYMORE.
THERE IS SO MUCH EFFORT
BEING PUT INTO THE
INVESTIGATION.
THEY MIGHT SAY, IT WILL
NEVER BE JUSTICE.
WHAT IS --
[INAUDIBLE]
>> THE ANSWERS ARE FOR THE
POOR VICTIMS, FAMILIES,
PEOPLE OF CONNECTICUT THAT
NEED TO KNOW AND SEE A CLEAR
PICTURE EXACTLY WHAT
HAPPENED HERE.
AS I SAID MANY TIMES, THERE
ARE MANY PEOPLE, INCLUDING
FIRST-RESPONDERS, INCLUDING
TOWN RESIDENTS, INCLUDING
PEOPLE RIGHT IN THIS
AUDIENCE THAT HAVE BROKEN
HEARTS OVER THIS AND WE'RE
GOING TO DO EVERYTHING THAT
IT TAKES TO INSURE THAT WE
UNCOVER EVERY BIT OF
EVIDENCE, THAT WE EXAMINE
EVERY FACET OF IT.
THAT WE CONDUCT AS MANY
INTERVIEWS WITH EVERYONE
THAT WE NEED TO DO TO PAINT
A CLEAR PICTURE AS TO
EXACTLY HOW AND WHY THIS
TRAGEDY OCCURRED.
YES, MA'AM?
>> CAN YOU CLARIFY THAT THE
MOTHER WAS SHOT WITH A .22
CALIBER RIFLE AND THERE WERE
OTHER GUNS IN THE HOUSE?
>> I CAN'T ANSWER THAT AGAIN,
MA'AM ANYTHING SEIZED IN THE
HOUSE WOULD BE EVIDENCE.
AS FAR AS THE WOUND THAT THE
VICTIM SUFFERED, THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER WAS VERY CLEAR, IT
WAS MULTIPLE GUNSHOT WOUNDS.
THAT'S AS FAR AS WE WENT
WITH THAT DESCRIPTION.
ONE MORE QUESTION, YES, SIR.
>> CAN YOU SPEAK ANYMORE
TO --
[INAUDIBLE]
>> THERE WAS NO CONNECTION
BETWEEN THE SHOOTER AND THE
SCHOOL ACCORDING TO THE
SCHOOL AUTHORITIES HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
>> NONE AT ALL?
>> ACCORDING TO THE SCHOOL
AUTHORITIES IN NEWTOWN.
>> CAN YOU ANSWER A QUESTION
ABOUT HE HAD SO MUCH
WEAPONRY AND HEARD ABOUT A
LOCKDOWN OF A SCHOOL NEARBY
TODAY?
>> WE ADDRESSED THAT BEFORE
AND I WILL JUST RESTATE
THAT.
THERE WAS, ANYTHING
WHATSOEVER TO DO WITH SCHOOL
SECURITY ANYWHERE WITHIN OUR
STATE, WE'RE OBVIOUSLY ALL
ON THE EDGE, WE'RE ALL ON
EDGE, ANYTHING THAT IS
SUSPICIOUS, ANYTHING THAT
EVEN REMOTELY APPEARS TO BE
A LACK OF SECURITY OR BREACH
OF SECURITY, ANY EDUCATIONAL
INSTITUTION IN CONNECTICUT
AND I'M SURE IN SURROUNDING
STATES AND ACROSS THE
COUNTRY WILL BE TREATED,
VERY, VERY SERIOUSLY.
THERE WAS A REPORT THIS
MORNING WHERE THERE WAS
SUSPICIOUS INDIVIDUAL IN
CLOSE PROXIMITY TO ONE OF
THE SCHOOLS.
THE LOCAL POLICE DEPARTMENT
RESPONDED, INVESTIGATED AND
CLEARED THE MATTER.
IT WAS NOT A THREAT, BUT IN
DOING SO THEY DID PUT NEARBY
SCHOOLS IN LOCKDOWN, SIMPLY
AS A PRECAUTION.
I DO KNOW ACROSS THE STATE,
THE GOVERNOR AND EDUCATION
COMMISSIONER AND LOCAL
AUTHORITIES AND LOCAL
OFFICIALS ARE PUTTING A
LITTLE BIT OF EXTRA
SECURITY.
WE'RE SUPPORTING THE
EDUCATIONAL SYSTEM
THROUGHOUT THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE CERTAINLY, AS YOU WELL
KNOW, THE TEACHERS ARE
WELL-TRAINED.
THE FACULTY ARE WELL-TRAINED,
ALL THE PERSONNEL IN THE
SCHOOL ARE WELL-TRAINED.
THEY PRACTICE FOR FIRE
DRILLS, FOR EMERGENCIES AND
BELIEF ME THE BLANKET OF
PUBLIC SECURITY WILL BE
STRICT IN THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT.
WHAT I WOULD LIKE TO SAY
TODAY, THIS IS GOING TO BE
OUR LAST PRESS GATHERING
TODAY.
WE HAVE COME TO A POINT IN
THIS INVESTIGATION, YES, WE
ARE STILL WORKING BUT I
DON'T WANT TO KEEP YOU HERE,
WANT TO KEEP COMING UP AND
TRYING TO GIVE YOU
INFORMATION IF WE HAVE NO
NEW INFORMATION TO GIVE YOU.
WHAT WE'RE GOING TO DO, I
HANDED OUT A SLIP THAT GIVES
YOU INFORMATION.
ANYTHING NEW IS GOING TO BE
POSTED ON OUR WEBSITE.
ALL PRESS RELEASES, ALL
PRESS ANNOUNCEMENTS WILL BE
POSTED ON OUR WEBSITE.
IF THERE WERE ANYTHING THATUPTEG
THIS INVESTIGATION AND WE
NEEDED TO HOLD A PRESS
CONFERENCE AND IT WOULD HAVE
TO BE SOMETHING SIGNIFICANT,
WE'LL GIVE YOU AMPLE TIME TO
GATHER AT A CENTRAL LOCATION
AND PROVIDE THAT BETWEEN THE
LIEUTENANT FROM NEWTOWN AND
MYSELF.
SO I AGAIN, AM IMPLORING YOU
TO PLEASE GIVE THE FAMILIES
PRIVACY AS THEY GO THROUGH
THIS VERY DEVASTATING PERIOD
OF TIME IN THEIR LIFE.
WE WILL STAY IN CONTACT.
IF YOU HAVE SPECIFIC
QUESTIONS WE CAN ADDRESS
THEM VIA E-MAIL, THAT WOULD
BE SMARTEST AND BEST WAY.
WE'LL BE MORE THAN HAPPY TO
ADDRESS THAT.
>> SINCE MIGHT BE A LONG
TIME TO GET A CHANCE TO TALK
TO YOU.
>> YES, SIR.
>> I'M WONDERING, THIS IS
KEY QUESTION WE ASK YOU ALL
THE TIME.
YOU KEEP REFERRING TO, CAN
YOU GIVE PEOPLE GUIDANCE AND
PEOPLE WHO MIGHT BE
WONDERING HOW LONG IT MIGHT
TAKE AND WHY IT TAKES SO
LONG AND HOW LONG WILL WE
HAVE TO WAIT BEFORE YOU COME
UP AND TELL JUST SO WE HAVE
SOME IDEA?
HUNDREDS OF INTERVIEWS,
FILING EACH PIECE OF
EVIDENCE ON EVERY TRAIL THAT
IT GUESS IT WILL TAKE
SUBSTANTIAL AMOUNT OF TIME,
I KNOW, WE KNOW AS
INVESTIGATORS, THAT THE
PEOPLE, CONNECTICUT, PEOPLE
OF THIS TOWN OF NEWTOWN,
WANT TO KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
WE'RE GOING TO DO THAT.
WE'RE GOING TO PROVIDE THEM
ANY INFORMATION AT ALL
INFORMATION.
WE'LL PAINT A CRYSTAL CLEAR
PICTURE AS MUCH AS WE
POSSIBLY CAN.
BUT IT IS A SLOW PROCESS.
IT IS NOT SOMETHING JUST
DONE IN 60 MINUTES AS YOU
SEE ON TV.
WE'LL KEEP THE PUBLIC
INFORMED.
WE WILL MAKE SURE THAT THERE
IS ANYTHING THAT IS EMERGENT,
THAT WE GET IT OUT
IMMEDIATELY AND IT'S THROUGH
YOU FOLKS.
I WANT TO THANK YOU FOR
EVERYTHING THAT YOU'VE DONE.
YOU FOLKS HAVE BEEN VERY
PROFESSIONAL AND WE DO
DEFINITELY APPRECIATE THAT.
ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU
JENNA: A FEW THINGS WE
SHOULD REVIEW WITH YOU, THAT
CAME TO LIGHT BASED ON WHAT
HE TOLD US.
THERE SHOULD BE A VIDEO HOUR
AGO OF LARGE MOVING TRUCKS
THAT CAME TO THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
WE WEREN'T SURE WHY THEY
WERE THERE.
WERE THEY COLLECTING
EVIDENCE, WAS SOMETHING ELSE
GOING ON?
THE LIEUTENANT TELLING US
SOME OF THAT FURNITURE IS
BEING MOVED.
POTENTIALLY SOME OF THESE
STUDENTS FROM SANDY HOOK,
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADERS MAY YOU WERE RETURN
TO A BUILDING SOMEWHERE IN
THE AREA.
THEY WILL SET UP A MAKESHIFT
SCHOOL, IF YOU WILL, AND
PERHAPS THAT IS WHERE SOME
OF THE FURNITURE IS GOING.
JON: HARD TO IMAGINE THEY
WOULD REOPEN THAT SCHOOL.
CERTAINLY NOT IN ITS CURRENT
CONFIGURATION.
THAT IS DECISION TO BE LEFT
DOWN THE ROAD AFTER
COLUMBINE.
THEY MADE SOME CHANGES IN
THE PHYSICAL FACILITIES
THERE.
DID A LOT OF REMODELING BUT
THIS IS AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
WHERE SUCH HORRORS HAVE
TAKEN PLACE, THERE ARE MANY
BIG DECISIONS AHEAD.
JENNA: WE SHOULD MENTION
THERE WILL BE ARMED GUARDS
ON THAT PROPERTY.
IT IS A CRIME SCENE