YOU ALL WILL COME TOGETHER AND
YOU LIVE ONE ANOTHER.
>> YOU SPEAK ELOQUENTLY TO THE
NATION.
THAT THE IMPORTANCE OF YOUR
FAITH IN COMMUNITY IN EMBRACING
EACH OTHER AND NOT JUST BY
PHYSICAL PRESENCE.
♪
>>> BRAND-NEW HOUR OF THE
CONTINUING COVERAGE OF THE
TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN WITH THE
PRESIDENT TO ARRIVE IN CONTRACT
CONNECTICUT.
WE'LL GET THERE.
WELCOME.
I'M RICK FOLBAUM.
>> I'M ARTHEL NEVIL.
THE PRESIDENT IS TO ADDRESS THE
NATION AT ONE OF THE WORST MASS
SHOOTINGS IN U.S. HISTORY.
IT'S THE FOURTH TRIP TO A SHAS
SHOOTING TO AN AMERICAN CITY.
GOING TO ED HENRY IN NEWTOWN
WITH THE LATEST.
ED, TELL US ABOUT THE
PRESIDENT'S EVENING THERE IN
CONNECTICUT, WHAT IS EXPECTED.
>> Reporter: AS THE MENTIONED
THE FIRST VISIT SINCE THE
TRAGEDY, REMEMBER THAT ALL THIS
LATEST OUT SO HORRIBLY AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WHICH IS STILL
BASICALLY A CRIME SEEN.
THE HIGH SCHOOL BEHIND ME IS
WHERE THERE WILL BE AN
INTERFAITH PRAYER SERVICE WHERE
THE PRESIDENT WILL SPEAK, REALLY
THE FIRST TIME SINCE WE SAW HIM
FRIDAY CHOKE BACK TEARS AT THE
WHITE HOUSE AS HE TALKED ABOUT
THIS AWFUL TRAGEDY.
HE WILL BE MEETING BEFORE THE
INTERFAITH PRAYER SERVICE WITH
FAMILIES OF SOME OF THE VICTIMS,
SO MANY OF THE VICTIMS SO YOUNG.
VERY DIFFICULT.
ALSO, HE'LL BE MEETING WITH THE
FIRST RESPONDERS TO THANK THEM
FOR ALL THEY HAVE DONE NOT JUST
IN THE IMMEDIATE AFTERMATH OF
THE TRAGEDY BUT SINCE THEN.
I SPOKE WITH SOMEONE FROM THE
RED CROSS, A GENTLEMAN FROM
NORTH CAROLINA.
HE SAYS THERE IS ABOUT HUNDRED
RED CROSS VOLUNTEERS, HELPING
THE CLERGY AND HELPING OTHERS
COPE WITH THIS.
THAT IS WHAT THE RED CROSS AND
MAJORITY AND OTHERS ARE DOING IS
BASIC COUNSELING SERVICES.
>> PRESIDENTIAL, OF COURSE, BUT
IT SEEMS HIS ADVICE SIT PERSONAL
AS WELL AND CERTAINLY WE'RE
HEARING POLITICIANS TALKING
ABOUT GUN CONTROL.
DO WE THINK THE PRESIDENT IS
GOING TO TOUCH ON THAT AT ALL.
>> I'M TOLD THE PRESIDENT WILL
NOT BE TOUCHING ON THOSE ISSUES.
A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE TALKING
ABOUT GUN CONTROL AND MENTAL
HEALTH CONTROL ISSUES.
PRESIDENT BELIEVES THAT IS NOT
THE TIME NOR THE PLACE AT THE
INTERFAITH SERVICE TO DISCUSS
THOSE.
HE WILL FOCUS HIS REMARKS ON
PRAYER AND REMEMBRANCE.
THOSE REMARKS ON FRIDAY.
THE PRESIDENT SUGGESTED ON
FRIDAY IN DAYS AND WEEKS AHEAD
HE BELIEVES ACTION NEEDS TO BE
TAKEN.
HE WAS PRESSED ON SOME OF THESE
SUNDAY SHOWS.
MAYOR MICHAEL BLOOMBERG SAYING
NOW IS THE TIME TO ACT AND NOT A
VAGUE PROMISE, HE NEEDS TO
FOLLOW-UP ON GUN CONTROL.
THERE ARE OTHERS WAIT A SECOND,
DON'T TRY TO CAPITALIZE WITH
SOME SORT OF LEGISLATION THAT
MAY NOT BE THE RIGHT
PRESCRIPTION.
THERE WILL BE A BIG DEBATE BUT
I'M TOLD THE PRESIDENT WILL NOT
TALK ABOUT THAT INSTEAD TALKING
ABOUT PRAYER AND REMEMBRANCE.
ON FRIDAY HE SAID HE AND FIRST
LADY WOULD HUG THEIR OWN
CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER THIS
WEEKEND.
BEFORE THE PRESIDENT IS HEADING
TO CONNECTICUT JUST A SHORT TIME
AGO HE WAS AT HIS DAUGHTER'S
DANCE REHEARSAL THAT IS COMING
UP.
HE IS THINKING ABOUT ALL OF THIS
AS A PARENT AND NOT JUST AS A
PRESIDENT.
>> AS WE WERE SPEAKING, HE IS IN
FACT ON THE WAY THERE.
WE ARE LOOKING AT LIVE PICTURES
THE ANDREWS AIR FORCE BASE.
I WANTED TO GET BACK TO OUR
DISCUSSION, YOU SAID THAT YOU
DON'T ANTICIPATE THE PRESIDENT
TO ADDRESS THE ISSUE OF GUN
CONTROL
I WOULD IMAGINE, YOU ARE THERE
ON THE GROUND, I WOULD IMAGINE
AT THIS POINT THE PARENTS THERE,
PEOPLE IN THAT COMMUNITY AREN'T
NECESSARILY LOOKING FOR THE
PRESIDENT TO ISSUE THOSE WORDS
OR TO TALK ABOUT THAT TOPIC
SWNROOR THEY ARE NOT.
YOU ARE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
I MET A GENTLEMAN THAT HELPED US
PARK IN FRONT OF THE HIGH SCHOOL
THE BUILDING BEHIND ME AS SOME
OF THE SECURITY TIGHTENING
ANTICIPATING THE PRESIDENT'S
RIVAL AND I SPOKE TO THIS
GENTLEMAN.
HE KNEW TWO PEOPLE THAT WORKED
AT THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, ONE OF
THEM THE PRINCIPAL WHO SO
TRAGICALLY DIED.
HE SAID RIGHT NOW, A LOT OF
PEOPLE ARE TALKING ABOUT THE
FACT THE PRINCIPAL LIVES DOWN
THE STREET FROM WHERE I AM
BROADCASTING RIGHT NOW.
I SPOKE TO THIS GENTLEMAN AND HE
SAID HIS OWN SON, HIS YOUNG SON,
KNEW SOMEBODY AT THE SCHOOL WHO
THANKFULLY HAD NOT PERISHED
THERE, BUT HAD WAS AN EYEWITNESS
TO WHAT SOME OF WHAT HAD PLAYED
OUT.
WHILE THANKFUL WAS ALIVE WAS
STRUGGLING WHAT HE HEARD AND SUE
THAT DAY.
THEY ARE TALKING ABOUT WHAT
PLAYED OUT.
HOW THEY ARE COMING TOGETHER AS
A COMMUNITY.
AS I MENTIONED IT WILL BE A
GREAT DEBATE AND NOT TALKING
ABOUT THAT HERE TODAY.
>> Rick: WE'RE SEEING THE
PRESIDENT WHO STEPPED OFF MARINE
ONE TO HIS WAY TO AIR FORCE ONE
FOR HIS TRIP.
WE REMEMBER THE PEACH SPEECH HE
MADE IN THE AFTERMATH THAT
INVOLVED GABRIELLE GIFFORDS THE
SPEECH THAT A LOT OF PEOPLE
PRAISED IN WHICH HE TALKED ABOUT
DOING SOMETHING MEANINGFUL TO
PREVENT THESE KINDS OF THINGS
FROM HAPPENING AGAIN.
ALMOST THE SAME WORDS HE USED IN
THE REMARKS HE MADE ON FRIDAY
FROM THE WHITE HOUSE.
YET, THIS PRESIDENT HAS NOT
SUGGESTED ANYTHING SPECIFIC WHAT
THAT MIGHT MEAN MEANINGFUL.
WHAT ARE WHITE HOUSE AIDES
TELLING YOU BEHIND THE SCENES IF
HE IS NOT GOING TO MENTION
ANYTHING SPECIFIC TONIGHT IN
CONNECTICUT, AT WHAT POINT
SHOULD WE DPPT HIM TO TALK ABOUT
THOSE MEANINGFUL SOLUTIONS?
>> Reporter: AFTER THE TRAGIC
SHOOTING IN COLORADO AT THE
MOVIE THEATER, PRESIDENT WAS ON
THE SCENE AND TALKED AGAIN ABOUT
ACTION THAT COULD BE TAKEN.
HE IS FACING PRESSURE FROM MAYOR
BLOOMBERG AND OTHERS.
WHITE HOUSE AIDES ARE SAYING
PRIVATELY HE DOESN'T THINK IT'S
TIME TO JUMP ON IT IMMEDIATELY.
HE WANT TO TALK ABOUT HAVING THE
NATION COME TOGETHER.
THAT PRESSURE IS NOT GOING TO GO
AWAY ESPECIALLY FROM DEMOCRATS
THAT WANT TO SEE ACTION.
I HAVE SEEN THIS BEFORE WITH
OTHER PRESIDENTS BUT STEPPING
AWAY FROM GUN CONTROL.
PEOPLE MAKING ASSUMPTIONS BUT
ALL OF A SUDDEN THE PARTISANSHIP
IN WASHINGTON WILL DISAPPEAR.
YOU ARE RIGHT TO MENTION
GABRIELLE GIFFORDS, PRESIDENT
MADE DRAMATIC REMARKS IN TUCSON
ABOUT COMING TOGETHER.
WITHIN WEEKS IF TO THE DAYS,
BOTH PARTIES IN WASHINGTON WERE
FIGHTING IT OUT ON VARIOUS
ISSUES AND NOT NECESSARILY
COMING TOGETHER.
THE PRESIDENT SPOKE VERY
ELOQUENTLY ON FRIDAY.
YOU HEARD REPUBLICANS LIKE JOHN
BOEHNER NOTING THAT AND SAYING
HE SPOKE FOR THE ENTIRE NATION.
ON SATURDAY, NORMALLY YOU WOULD
HAVE THE REPUBLICANS GIVE THEIR
WEEKLY ADDRESS.
THIS WEEKEND, JOHN BOEHNER SAID
THAT IT WOULD BE TIME FOR THE
PRESIDENT TO SPEAK FOR THE
ENTIRE NATION.
NO REASON FOR A REPUBLICAN
RESPONSE.
YOU HAVE AT FISCAL CLIFF AND
OTHER ISSUES THAT WILL HAVE TO
BE FOUGHT OUT ON ANOTHER DAY.
THERE WILL BE SOME COMING
TOGETHER.
WE SAW INSTANCES LIKE THIS BRING
THE PARTIES TOGETHER BUT SPLIT
APART IN DAYS OR WEEKS LATER.
>> Rick: THANKS VERY MUCH.
>> WE WANT TO REMIND VIEWERS
TUNE IN TONIGHT 6:00 P.M.
EASTERN OF COVERAGE OF THE
PRESIDENT'S VISIT.
HE WILL BE ATTENDING AND
PROGRAMMING BE HOSTED BY BRET
BAIER, WATCH IT HAPPEN LIVE HERE
ON FOX.
>> Rick: FIRST FUNERAL FOR ONE
OF THE CHILDREN THAT WAS SHOT IS
SET FOR TOMORROW.
BOY'S UNCLE DESCRIBES HIM AS
SMART AS WHIP.
HIS TWIN SISTER WAS ALSO IN THE
SCHOOL AT THE TIME OF THE
SHOOTING BUT SHE WAS ASSIGNED TO
A DIFFERENT CLASSROOM.
SHE SURVIVED.
THE FAMILY SAYS HE CONSIDERS HIS
TWIN SISTER HIS BEST FRIEND AND
THEY WERE INSEPARABLE.
>> ANOTHER VICTIM WAS OLIVIA
ROSE, HER PARENTS SAID THEIR
DAUGHTER LOVED GOING TO SCHOOL.
SHE DID WELL IN MATH, READING
AND ART.
OLIVIA WAS ALSO EXPECTED TO TAKE
PART IN A CHURCH PERFORMANCE
LAST FRIDAY NIGHT.
SHE WAS TO PLAY THE PART OF AN
ANGEL.
COMING UP WE'LL HAVE A LIVE
REPORT WITH MORE STORIES OF THE
PRECIOUS LIVES LOST THERE.
>> Rick: AS THE NATION MOURNS
THE VICTIMS OF THIS TRAGEDY, WE
ARE LEARNING MORE DETAILS.
AUTHORITIES SAY THAT THE GUNMAN
SHOT HIS MOTHER MULTIPLE TIMES
IN THE HEAD BEFORE GOING TO THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WHERE HE
GUNNED DOWN ALL THOSE PEOPLE
INCLUDING 20 CHIN.
INVESTIGATORS ARE CHASING LEADS
THAT THEY HOPE MY CAST LIGHT ON
THE LIFE OF THIS GUNMAN.
TELL US THE LATEST ON THE
INVESTIGATION.
>> Reporter: THE LATEST ON THE
INVESTIGATION IS THERE WAS A LOT
OF ATTENTION MADE TO ONE WOUNDED
SURVIVOR.
POLICE SAID TODAY THEY, INDEED,
WERE TWO PEOPLE THAT WERE
WOUNDED MADE IT OUT OF THAT
SCHOOL.
THEY HAVE BEEN CON N CONTACT
WITH POLICE.
A LOST ATTENTION WAS PAID TO TO
THREE DIFFERENT WEAPONS USED IN
THAT ASSAULT, ASSAULT WILDLIFE
AND TWO SIDE ARMS.
POLICE INDICATED THAT THERE WERE
FOUR WEAPONS, ONE LONG WILDLIFE
AND THREE SIDE ARMS BUT THEY DID
NOT SAY ALL THE SIDE WARMS WERE
FOUND IN ONE LOCATION.
THEY ARE GATHERING EVIDENCE AND
INFORMATION RELATED TO A MOTIVE
BUT NOT RELEASING ANY PARTIAL
INFORMATION ABOUT THE BIG
QUESTION, THE REASON WHY THIS
HAPPENED.
>> WE HAVE TO COMPLETE THE
INVESTIGATION.
WE HAVE TO HAVE THE WHOLE
PICTURE BEFORE WE CAN SAY
HOPEFULLY HOW AND WHY THIS
OCCURRED.
THAT IS NOT GOING TO COME VERY
QUICKLY.
>> Reporter: AND FINAL AUTOPSIES
WERE PERFORMED ON THE LAST TWO
BODIES TAKEN FROM THE CRIME
SCENES.
THOSE WERE THE BODIES OF THE
MOTHER, NANCY AND THE GUNMAN
HIMSELF.
THERE IS NOW INFORMATION COMING
FROM THE MEDICAL EXAMINER THAT
THE MOTHER WAS SHOT MULTIPLE
TIMES IN THE HEAD.
WE'VE GOT A REPORT THROUGH THE
ASSOCIATED PRESS SHE WAS SHOT
FOUR TIMES AND STILL WEARING
PAJAMAS IN BED WHEN POLICE
ARRIVED ON THE SECOND CRIME
SCENE.
THE GUNMAN AS YOU MAY HAVE
PREDICTED DIED FROM A SINGLE
GUNSHOT WOUND TO THE HEAD.
>> Rick: SO THE POLICE OBVIOUSLY
WITH THEIR HANDS FULL REGARDING
THOSE TWO CRIME SCENES BUT THEY
HAVE TO DEAL WITH TROUBLEMAKERS?
>> IT REALLY SEEMS THAT WAY.
DURING MATH TODAY THERE WAS
THREAT CALLED IN TO THE ST. ROSE
CATHOLIC CHURCH.
THIS HAS BECOME SUCH AN
IMPORTANT PLACE FOR COMMUNITY TO
GET TOGETHER.
DURING MASS TODAY A THREAT WENT
TO HARM INDIVIDUALS INSIDE THAT
CHURCH ACCORDING TO A SPOKESMAN.
OUT OF AN ABUNDANCE OF CAUTION
THE CHURCH WAS EVACUATED AND
STATE TROOPERS ARRIVING STORMING
INTO THE CHURCH ITSELF BUT A
COUPLE SURROUNDING BUILDINGS.
THERE IS DELIBERATE
MISINFORMATION GOING OUT OVER
THE INTERNET.
THEY SAY THERE ARE PEOPLE
GETTING ON THE INTERNET POSING
AS THE GUNMAN HIMSELF AND
PUTTING OUT INFORMATION.
ALSO MAKING IT LOOK LIKE THEY
ARE PUTTING OUT OFFICIAL RE
LEASES.
STATE THERE POLICE AND FEDERAL
INVESTIGATORS ARE TAKING THAT
VERY SERIOUSLY.
>> THE INFORMATION CAN IN FACT
HAS IN FACT IS THREATENING.
IT'S BEEN INACCURATE.
PEOPLE POSING AS OTHER PEOPLE
AND DISCUSSING WITH FEDERAL
AUTHORITIES, THEY BELIEVE IS
VIOLATION OF STATE OR FEDERAL
LAW AND WARRANTS AN
INVESTIGATION.
ANYBODY THAT IS PERPETRATED THAT
GO INFORMATION COULD IN FACT BE
SUBJECT TO ARREST AND BE
PROSECUTED FEDERALLY.
>> Reporter: DISCUSSION NEEDS TO
BE HAD IS GETTING SURVIVING
STUDENTS BACK INTO CLASS SCHOOL
BOARD SAID THEY WILL GO BACK TO
ANOTHER SCHOOL, A NEARBY SCHOOL
CHALK HILL SCHOOL THAT IS
CURRENTLY EMPTY BUT THEY ARE NOT
SPECIFYING WHEN THE STUDENTS
WILL BE BACK IN SCHOOL.
>> Rick: MIKE, THANKS SO MUCH.
>> SCHOOL SECURITY TAKING CENTER
STAGE IN THE WAKE OF THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY AS PARENTS PREPARE TO
TAKE THEM BACK TO SCHOOL IN THE
MORNING.
MANY OF THEM ARE WONDERING WHAT
CAN BE DONE TO MAKE SURE THEIR
CHILDREN ARE SAFE.
DOMINIC?
>> Reporter: THE MEASURES TO
KEEP SCHOOL SAFE ARE WELL
ESTABLISHED.
THEY ARE SAYING WHAT IS NEEDED
IS GREAT IMPLEMENTATION BY
SCHOOLS AND BETTER COORDINATION
WITH AUTHORITIES AND THEY SAY
THAT IS NOT HARD TO DO.
>> WE DON'T NEED TO TEACH
KINDERGARTENERS THROW THINGS BUT
WE NEED TO FOCUS ON TRAINING
YOUR STAFF, HAVING LOCK DOWN
DRILLS, WORKING COOPERATIVELY
WITH POLICE THAT TAKE MORE TIME
THAN THEY DO MONEY.
>> Reporter: THERE HAVE BEEN
ANOTHER CUTS IN SCHOOL BUDGETS
IN FEDERAL AND LOCAL LEVELS BUT
EXPERTS WE JUST HEARD FROM WE
MAY NEED MORE MONEY FOR RADIOS
OR POLICE OFFICERS OR EXTRA
COUNSELOR, MANY DON'T REQUIRE
MONEY AND THEY REQUIRE TIME.
GOOD EXAMPLE IN MANY SCHOOLS
ONLY ADMINISTRATORS CAN ORDER A
LOCKDOWN.
THAT SHOULD CHANGED.
>> THAT IS UNACCEPTABLE.
IF YOU ARE IN A SCHOOL WHERE
ONLY YOUR ADMINISTRATOR IS
ALLOWED TO DO A LOCKDOWN, THEN
WE NEED TO HAVE SOME TRAINING TO
EMPOWER YOU AND TRAIN YOU ON HOW
TO DO ONE YOURSELF.
BECAUSE ANY ADULT IN THAT
BUILDING THAT SEES A DANGEROUS
SITUATION SHOULD BE ABLE TO
CARRY OUT A LIFE SAVING
FUNCTION.
>> Reporter: AND ADULTS LIKE THE
JANITOR OR NON-TEACHERS.
ALL THE EXPERTS WE SPOKEN TO TO
MAKE SURE THAT SCHOOL SAFETY IS
PREVENTION AND CRISIS PLANNING
AND REALLY PART OF THE TRAINING
AGENDA FOR EDUCATING
PROFESSIONALS.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I WANT TO LET YOU KNOW.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE A LOT MORE
WITH KEN TRUMP, PRESIDENT OF
NATIONAL SCHOOL SAFETY AND
SECURITY SERVICES.
>> Rick: THE STORY OF A SIMILAR
TRAGEDY SOON TO GET LOST IN THE
SHUFFLE.
ONE THAT HAD A MUCH DIFFERENT
ENDING.
HOURS BEFORE THE NEWTOWN
MASSACRE, A MAN BURST INTO A
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN CHINA AND
ATTACKED 22 CHILDREN AND ALONG
WITH AN ELDERLY WOMAN BUT RATHER
THAN USE A RIFLE THIS MAN HAD
ONLY A KNIFE.
NOT ONE PERSON WAS KILLED.
ALL WERE SLASHED AND INJURED BUT
THEY ALSO ALL SURVIVED.
A MASSIVE TRAGEDY AVERTED THERE.
SUCH A DIFFERENT STORY HERE.
POLICE IN CHINA SAY THE MAN THAT
WAS APPARENTLY MENTALLY 81 NOW
IN CUSTODY.
>> NOW THE VICTIMS IN CHINA MAY
HAVE SURVIVED, AMERICA IS COMING
TO TERMS WITH THE LOSS OF 26
LIVES AS TEACHERS, PARENTS AND
NEIGHBORS STRUGGLE TO MAKE SENSE
OF THIS SENSELESS CRIME FOR
THEMSELVES AS WELL AS THE KIDS
WHO HAVE TO RETURN TO AMERICAN
SCHOOL SYSTEM THIS WEEK THAT
WILL LIKELY BE FOREVER CHANGED.
>> IT'S BEING A TEACHER AND
HAVING TO TALK WITH MY KIDS WHAT
WAS HAPPENING WHILE WE WERE
WATCHING ONLINE UNFOLD.
NOT ALLOWING THEM TO HAVE SAFETY
ANYMORE, THEY SHOULD BE ABLE TO
GO TO SCHOOL.
>> THIS IS HORRIBLE, LITTLE KIDS
DON'T KNOW THE MEANING, THEY
DON'T KNOW DANGER.
♪
Hmm, it says here that Cheerios
helps lower cholesterol
as part
of a heart healthy diet.
That's true.
...But you still have to go
to the gym.
♪ The one and only, Cheerios
GIVES YOU 1% CASH BACK
ON ALL PURCHASES,
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS.
AND EVERYONE LIKES 50% MORE...
[ Midwestern/Chicago accent ]
CHEDDAR! YEAH!
50 PERCENT MORE
[yodeling] YODEL-AY-EE-OO.
50% MORE FLASH.
[ Southern accent ]
50 PERCENT MORE TATERS.
THAT'S WHERE TOTS COME FROM.
[ Male Announcer ] THE
Capital One Cash Rewards Card
GIVES YOU
1% CASH BACK
ON EVERY
PURCHASE
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS
ON THE CASH YOU EARN.
IT'S THE CARD FOR PEOPLE
WHO LIKE MORE CASH.
50% MORE SPY STUFF.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
THIS CAR IS TOO SMALL.
often comes with a set
of equally impressive
instructions ?
Shouldn't something
that's truly advanced,
not need much explanation
at all ?
With the Nokia Lumia 822
on Verizon,
there's not much to learn
because it's
powered by Windows...
to let you do more than you ever
imagined on your smartphone.
Exclusively with Data Sense--
a feature that makes
the most of your plan.
Only on Verizon.
YOU WON'T TAKE OUR FUTURE.
AIDS AFFECTS US ALL.
EVEN BABIES.
CHEVRON IS WORKING TO STOP
MOTHER-TO-CHILD TRANSMISSION.
OUR EMPLOYEES AND THEIR FAMILIES
ARE PART OF THE FIGHT.
AND WE'RE WINNING.
AT CHEVRON NIGERIA, WE HAVEN'T
HAD A REPORTED CASE IN 12EARS.
AIDS IS STRONG.
BUT WE ARE STRONGER.
AND AIDS...
♪
AIDS IS GOING TO LOSE.
>>.
>> Arthel: AS THE NATION GRIEVES
FOR THE LIVES LOST, STORIES OF
HERISM ARE EMERGING LIKE
29-YEAR-OLD TEACHER WHOSE QUICK
THINKING SAVED THE LIVES OF 14
STUDENTS.
>> SHE HAD TO DO THIS TO SAVE
HERSELF AND HER KIDS TO GET INTO
THE BATHROOM.
SHE SHUT HER DOOR.
SHE TURNED OFF THE LIGHTS.
SHE TRIED TO BLOCK THE BATHROOM
DOOR A LITTLE BIT.
SHE JUST DID IT.
ASKED THEM TO BE QUIET.
THEY WERE REMARKABLE KIDS.
>> I'M REALLY PROUD OF HER.
>> Arthel: ONE OF MANY REASONS
WHY WE LOVE TEACHERS.
POLICE KNOCKED ON THE DOOR,
KAITLIN REFUSED TO RESPOND UNTIL
POLICE SLID THEIR BADGES
UNDERNEATH THE BATHROOM DOOR.
>> Rick: NEW STUDY BY THE
CONSUMER FINANCIAL PROTECTION
BUREAU SHOWING WHEN RATING OUT
PERSONAL CREDIT SCORES, RATINGS
RELY ON CREDIT CARD USE AS
OPPOSED TO RENT OR TUITION OR
CAR LOANS.
THIS IS BAD NEWS AT A TIME WHEN
A LOT OF US ARE LOADING UP ON
CREDIT CARDS TO COVER HOLIDAY
SHOPPING LISTS.
JOINING US IS BRENDA BUTTNER,
ANCHOR OF "BULLS AND BEARS."
THANKS FOR BEING HERE.
BOTTOM LINE IF YOU WANT A GOOD
CREDIT SCORE, TAKE CARE OF YOUR
CREDIT CARD BILL?
>> IT'S AMAZING HOW MUCH WEIGHS
ON CREDIT SCORES.
58%, COMPARE TO MORTGAGE LENDERS
TO 7% AS WELL AS EDUCATIONAL
LENDERS.
SO TAKING CARE OF YOUR CREDIT IS
INCREDIBLY IMPORTANT.
IT'S IMPORTANT IF YOU WANT TO
RENTED A HOME OR ANY KIND OF
LOAN AT ALL.
IT'S REALLY IMPORTANT.
>> Rick: WHAT HAPPENS IF YOU
HAVE A BAD CREDIT SCORE, YOU HAD
A ROUGH AS SO MANY PEOPLE IN A
ROUGH ECONOMY AND YOU FELL
BEHIND A LITTLE BIT.
YOUR CREDIT SCORE HAS DIPPED.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN FOR YOU?
>> THAT MEANS IT'S GOING TO BE
REALLY HARD TO GET A LOAN.
IT WILL BE HARD TO RENT A PLACE.
IT AFFECTS ANYTHING, IF YOU WANT
TO BORROW OR GET CREDIT, IT WILL
IMPACT YOUR ABILITY TO DO SO.
BASICALLY WHAT THE CREDIT SCORE
LOOKS AT IS YOUR ABILITY TO
REPAY A DEBT.
IF YOU HAVEN'T BEEN REPAYING
DEBT PARTICULARLY ON CREDIT CARD
SOMEONE IS GOING TO LOOK AT THAT
AND LOW CREDIT SCORE.
BECAUSE OF THAT, WHY SHOULD ERIC
GIVING THEM MONEY IF THEY ARE
NOT WILLING TO PAY IT BACK IN
THE PAST.
>> Rick: LET'S TALK ABOUT
BALANCES.
EVERYBODY GETS A STATEMENT.
YOU CAN PAY THE MINIMUM AMOUNT
OR YOU CAN PAY IT OFF IN FULL.
AS FAR AS MAINTAINING GOOD
CREDIT SCORE WHAT IS THING TO
DO?
>> DEFINITELY PAY OFF THE
MINIMUM.
IF YOU CAN'T PAY THAT OFF THAT
IS GOING TO GIVE YOU A BLACK
SPOT ON YOUR CREDIT REPORT.
IF YOU HAVE THE ABILITY TO PAY
OFF THE BALANCE, OF COURSE, THAT
IS THE BEST THING TO DO FROM A
PERSONAL FINANCE STANDPOINT
BECAUSE YOU ARE GOING TO AVOID
ALL THE INTERESTED FEES.
IT DOESN'T IMPACT YOUR CREDIT
SCORES YOU ARE GOING TO GET OUT
OF HOLE A LITTLE BIT QUICKER.
>> Rick: WHAT ABOUT FOLKS THAT
ARE BUYING CHRISTMAS PRESENTS
AND STORE SAYS WOULD YOU LIKE TO
GET ONE OF OUR STORE CREDIT
CARDS.
WE'LL TAKE 30% OFF YOUR PURCHASE
TODAY.
>> MOST PEOPLE DO BECAUSE YOU
GET A DISCOUNTED.
THE PROBLEM IS IF YOU ARE NOT
GOING TO VIGILANT ABOUT
MAINTAINING THESE RETAIL CARDS,
IT'S REALLY GOING TO COST YOU
MORE IN THE END THAN JUST THAT
LITTLE DISCOUNT THAT YOU GET.
UNFORTUNATELY DURING THESE HARD
TIMES WE'RE DISCOVERING THAT
PEOPLE ARE REALLY USING THEIR
CREDIT CARDS FOR MORE THAN JUST
WANTS AND NEEDS, 30% ARE BUYING
THINGS LIKE GROCERY AND PAYING
UTILITY BILLS ON CREDIT CARDS.
>> Rick: MAYBE A GOOD IDEA
DURING THE HOLIDAY SHOPPING
SEASON TO PUT THE CREDIT CARD
AWAY AND BUY THINGS WITH CASH.
I WANTED TO GO BACK TO THE IDEA
OF THE CREDIT SCORE.
YOU MIGHT BE ABLE TO GET CREDIT
OR GET A LOAN BUT THE INTEREST
RATES MIGHT GO UP?
>> RIGHT.
THAT IS ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
YOU CAN STILL GET A LOAN BUT YOU
WILL PAYING A LOT MORE.
IT'S BASICALLY THE PRICE OF
MONEY.
THAT IS WHAT CREDIT IS.
>> Rick: SO PEOPLE WHO HAVE
TAKEN A HIT ON THEIR CREDIT
SCORE, HOW LONG DOES IT TAKE TO
DIG OUT OF THAT?
>> YOU CAN DO IT.
JUST MAKE EIGHT RESOLUTION FOR
NEXT YEAR TO START PAYING OFF
THE MINIMUM FOR EXAMPLE.
IT DOESN'T TAKE SO LONG EVERY
MONTH IF IT IS CONSISTENT, THAT
IS KEY.
>> Rick: BRENDA BUTTNER, YOU CAN
SEE "BULLS AND BEARS" SATURDAY
MORNING AT 10:00.
THANKS SO MUCH.
>> Arthel: THE FAMILIES OF THE
VICTIMS OF THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL SHOOTING IS NOW SPEAKING
OUT AND THE STORIES AND WHAT
THEY WANT TO KNOW ABOUT THEIR
CHILDREN.
A LIVE REPORT FROM NEWTOWN
STRAIGHT AHEAD.
>>
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS SHELDO WHOSE LONG DAY
SETTING UP THE NEWS
STARTS WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND A CHOICE.
TAKE TYLENOL OR TAKE ALEVE,
THE #1 RECOMMENDED PAIN
RELIEVER BY ORTHOPEDIC DOCTORS.
JUST TWO ALEVE
CAN KEEP PAIN AWAY ALL DAY.
BACK TO THE NEWS.
>>.
>> Arthel: WELCOME BACK.
WE'RE GOING TO GET BACK TO
DEVELOPMENTS IN NEWTOWN IN JUST
A MOMENT.
CONGRESSIONAL HEARINGS ON
BENGHAZI TERROR ATTACKS GETTING
UNDERWAY NEXT WEEK BUT WITHOUT
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON TAKING PART IN THEM.
STATE DEPARTMENT SAYS SHE WILL
NOT TESTIFY BECAUSE SHE SUFFERED
A CONCUSSION FOLLOWING A FALL.
STILL, HEARINGS WILL GO ON AND
CHAIRWOMAN IS MAKING IT CLEAR
SHE WANTS SECRETARY CLINTON TO
TESTIFY AT SOME POINT.
SHE JOINS ME NOW.
GOOD TO SEE YOU CONGRESSWOMAN.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON.
>> Arthel: AT THIS POINT WE HAVE
TWO SENATOR STATE DEPARTMENT
OFFICIALS SET TO TESTIFY AND
SECRETARY CLINTON'S PLACE.
DO YOU THINK THEY ARE SUFFICIENT
PROXIES OR ONLY SECRETARY OF
STATE CAN PROVIDE SATISFYING
ANSWERS AND ONLY HER?
>> WE CERTAINLY WISH THE
SECRETARY A FULL AND SPEEDY
RECOVERY, BUT IT'S A DEEP
DISAPPOINTMENT NOT ONLY TO THE
MEMBERS OF OUR FOREIGN AFFAIRS
COMMITTEE BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY
TO THE AMERICAN PEOPLE SHE WILL
NOT BE THERE TO ANSWER FOR THE
TERRORIST ATTACK IN BENGHAZI,
LIBYA THAT RESULTED IN THE
MURDER OF FOUR AMERICANS,
STEVENS, SMITH, WOODS AND
DOHERTY.
THESE WERE BRAVE AMERICANS THAT
WERE SERVING OUR NATION AND AN
ATTACK ON OUR CONSULATE IS AN
ATTACK ON AMERICA.
IN THIS, WE WILL HAVE TWO OF HER
DEPUTIES, PHIL BURNS AND
TOM NIES AND THEY WILL PROVIDE A
REPORT ABOUT HOW TO PREVENT A
FUTURE BENGHAZI.
THEY ARE NOT A SUBSTITUTE FOR
THE SECRETARY.
WE HAVE ASKED HERSELF TO MAKE
AVAILABLE TO THE COMMITTEE ONCE
SHE RECOVERS.
DAY BEFORE OPEN HEARING WE WILL
BE HEARING FROM THE TWO
GENTLEMEN THAT WERE IN CHARGE OF
REVIEW, TOM PICKERING AND
AMBASSADOR MULLEN.
THEY WILL PROVIDE THIS IN A
CLASSIFIED SETTING BECAUSE THE
REPORT WILL NOT BE MADE PUBLIC
DUE TO SECURITY CONCERNS.
THAT HAS BEEN THE PROBLEM WITH
THE ADMINISTRATION.
THEY WANTED TO HAVE ALL OF THE
HEARINGS AND ALL OF THE
BRIEFINGS IN A SECURED SETTING
BUT THE AMERICAN PEOPLE WANT TO
KNOW WHAT THE STATE DEPARTMENT
AND ALL OF OUR AGENCIES ARE
DOING TO KEEP OUR DIPLOMATS
SAFE.
WE ALL DESERVE AN OPEN ANSWER IN
A TRANSPARENT SETTING.
>> Arthel: IS IT POSSIBLE FOR
YOU AND YOUR COLLEAGUES TO HEAR
AND COLLECT ALL THE INFORMATION
AT THESE HEARINGS, AND THEN
PROPERLY INFORM THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE SO THAT IN THE EVENT THAT
RAW TESTIMONY, IF YOU WILL, SOME
SECRETS ARE NOT DIVULGED.
IS THAT POSSIBLE SO THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE WON'T FEEL CHEATED IN THE
END?
>> THAT IS AN EXCELLENT
QUESTION.
THIS IS AMERICAN TAXPAYER
DOLLARS AT WORK.
THEY ARE FUNDING THE OPERATIONS,
NOT JUST THE CONSULATE AND THE
EMBASSIES BUT ALSO THE SECURITY
IN OUR ISLAND OF DEMOCRACY.
WE WANT TO MAKE SURE AMERICAN
TAXPAYER DOLLARS ARE USED WISELY
WE DON'T NEED TO SPEND MORE
MONEY.
WE NEED TO SPEND THE MONEY WE
HAVE IN A BETTER WAY.
IN BENGHAZI THE REPORTS WE HAVE
HEARD THAT THERE WERE CALLS AND
THEY WERE VERY CLEAR REQUESTS
FOR ADDED SECURITY.
THOSE REQUESTS WERE NOT HEEDED.
I KNOW THAT CONGRESS WOULD HAVE
FULLY FUNDED ANY OF THESE
SECURITY REQUESTS.
WE WANT TO USE TAXPAYER DOLLARS
WISELY.
>> Arthel: WE'RE SHORT ON TIME.
I KNOW THAT THOSE ARE THE POINTS
YOU WANT TO HAVE ANSWERED FOR
SURE.
I KNOW THAT YOU ARE VERY ADAMANT
ABOUT HEARING FROM SECRETARY OF
STATE CLINTON.
HAVE YOU HEARD ANY INFORMATION
FROM HER OFFICE THAT SHE MIGHT
BE ABLE TO TALK TO THE SPECIAL
HEARINGS?
HOW DOES THAT WORK?
>> WE HAVE MADE IT VERY CLEAR TO
HER OFFICE THAT WE DO EXPECT HER
TO TESTIFY.
SHE HAS EVERY EXPECTATION SHE
WILL BE TESTIFYING, BUT
UNFORTUNATELY AS YOU KNOW, SHE
HAS ALREADY STATED SHE WILL BE
STEPPING DOWN.
THERE ARE PRETTY GOOD REPORTS
THAT SENATOR KERRY WHO IS NOW
HEADING THE SENATE FOREIGN
RELATIONS COMMITTEE WILL BE
TAKING HER SPOT.
I FEAR BECAUSE OF THE SHUFFLE
THAT IS GOING ON WE MAY NOT BE
ABLE TO HEAR FROM SECRETARY
CLINTON ON THE BENGHAZI
TERRORIST ATTACK.
WE WILL BE A POORER NATION FOR
IT.
>> Arthel: THERE IS NO WAY
SECRETARY CLINTON STEPS DOWN AND
NEW SECRETARY OF STATE IS IN
PLACE, THERE IS NO WAY TO CALL
MRS. CLINTON BACK TO TESTIFY?
>> WE HOPE THAT SHE WILL FULFILL
HER DESIRE TO COME BEFORE OUR
COMMITTEE.
WE HOPE THAT WILL HAPPEN.
THEY HAVE NOT SHUT THE DOOR ON
THAT, BUT I KNOW AS ROBERT FROST
SAYS, WHO KNOWS WHAT WILL
HAPPEN.
WE HAVE EVERY EXPECTATION SHE
WILL.
THAT IS OUR STRICT REQUEST AND
WE HOPE SHE MAKES GOOD ON IT.
>> Arthel: IS THERE ANY WAY TO
ENSURE THAT THESE HEARINGS WILL
NOT BE POLITICIZED?
IF YOU WANT THE AMERICAN PEOPLE
TO GET THE REAL ANSWERS YOU HAVE
TO KEEP POLITICS OUT OF IT.
>> IT'S VERY HARD TO KEEP
POLITICS OUT OF ANYTHING WE DO
IN CONGRESS.
WHAT WE'RE TALKING ABOUT IS
TERRORIST ATTACK WITH FOUR
AMERICANS LOST THEIR LIVES, EVEN
THOUGH THEY REQUESTED MORE
SECURITY AND MORE HELP.
WE WANT TO KNOW WHAT WENT WRONG
AND TO PREVENT ANOTHER BENGHAZI.
AMERICAN LIVES ARE AT STAKE ALL
OVER THE WORLD.
WE ARE TARGETS.
WE WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT
ANOTHER BENGHAZI IS NOT GOING TO
HAPPEN AND ONLY WAY YOU CAN DO
THAT IS EXAMINE WHAT HAPPENED
WITH THIS ONE.
>> Arthel: CONGRESSWOMAN, THANK
YOU VERY MUCH FOR YOUR TIME.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Rick: WE ARE LEARNING NEW
DETAILS ABOUT THE PRECIOUS LIVES
THAT WERE LOST IN THE SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL SHOOTING MASSACRE.
20 CHILDREN, EIGHT ADULTS.
MOLLY IS LIVE IN NEWTOWN.
THIS IS WHAT EVERYONE HAS BEEN
DREADING TO HAVE TO LEARN ABOUT
THESE LIVES THAT WERE ENDED SO
SOON.
>> WE'RE JUST BEGINNING TO HEAR
ABOUT THE SIX WOMEN AND 20
CHILDREN WHOSE LIVES WERE TAKEN
IN THIS MASSACRE, STOLEN AWAY
FROM THEIR FRIENDS AND LOVED
ONES.
SIX-YEAR-OLD EMILY PARKER, SHE
WAS BIG SISTER.
HER GRIEVING FATHER, ROBBIE
PARKER DESCRIBED HER AS A LITTLE
GIRL, BLONDE AND ALWAYS SMILING.
SHE WAS A BUDDING ARTIST WHO
WOULD SPREAD HER KINDNESS
THROUGH DRAWINGS AND ALWAYS KEPT
ART SUPPLIES NEARBY.
>> OLIVIA WAS JUST SIX YEARS
OLD.
FAMILY AND FRIENDS HAVE CREATED
A MEMORIAL FUND ON FACEBOOK.
THAT IS FILLED WITH CHRISTMAS
THEMED PHOTOS.
OTHER FAMILIES ARE ALSO
SUFFERING BUT THEIR CHILDREN
SURVIVED.
EARLIER THIS MORNING ON FOX NEWS
SUNDAY.
ROBERT HAD A CHANCE TO SPEAK
WITH KRIS WALLACE.
HIS SON WAS -- CHRIS WALLACE.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> THE CHILDREN WITNESSED THE
SHOOTER COMING INTO THE ROOM,
SHOOT HIS TEACHER, CONTINUE
FIRING, THE CHILDREN ACTED ON
INSTINCTS AND WHAT THEY WERE
TAUGHT AND TO RUN.
THEY DID, THEY JUST RAN OFF TO
THE MAIN ROAD, HUNDRED YARDS
AWAY.
MY SON AND SEVERAL OTHER
STUDENTS WERE EXTREMELY BRAVE IN
WHAT THEY DID.
>> Reporter: MANY OF THE PARENTS
WHOSE CHILDREN SURVIVED FEEL A
SENSE OF BEING FORTUNATE BUT AT
THE SAME TIME IT'S A BITTERSWEET
FEELING BECAUSE THEY KNOW SO
MANY OTHER PARENTS ARE SUFFERING
SUCH EXTREME GRIEF.
>> Rick: MOLLY, THANK YOU.
>> Arthel: AND AMID THAT SORROW
AND GRIEF THE QUESTION MANY ARE
ASKING THIS WEEKEND, WHAT SET
THE GUNMAN ON THE PATH THAT MADE
HIM COMMIT ONE OF THE MOST
INFAMOUS CRIMES IN HISTORY.
A FORMER DETECTIVE WITH THE
NEW YORK POLICE DEPARTMENT.
GOOD MORNING, PATRICK.
POLICE ARE COLLECT VERY GOOD
GOOD EVIDENCE THEY GOT AT HIS
HOME.
WHAT ARE AUTHORITIES MAY BE
LOOKING FOR AT THIS POINT?
>> THEY ARE TRYING TO
RECONSTRUCT NOT JUST THE
MOVEMENTS GOING BACKWARDS OF
ADAM BUT HIS ENTIRE LIFESTYLE.
THEY WANT TO CONNECT THE DOTS
AND TIE TOGETHER E-MAILS AND
VOICEMAIL MESSAGES.
TO RECONSTRUCT NOT ONLY HOW IT
HAPPENED BUT WHY IT HAPPENED.
>> Arthel: THAT IS THE QUESTION
WE ARE HOPING TO FIND SOME
ANSWERS TO.
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE ALSO
SAYING THERE IS A WOMAN WHO WAS
WOUNDED IN THE SHOOTING.
SAYING THAT SHE IS INSTRUMENTAL
IN THE INVESTIGATION AT THIS
POINT.
WHO MIGHT ELSE BE ABLE TO HELP
PROVIDE CRUCIAL INFORMATION AT
THIS TIME?
>> THE WOMAN THAT THEY ARE
REFERRING TO IS THE VICE
PRINCIPAL THAT SURVIVED WHEN THE
PSYCHOLOGIST AND PRINCIPAL
LUNGED LEFT SIDE AT THE SHOOTER.
THEY HAVE OTHER THINGS, WHAT IN
PARTICULAR WHAT HE SAID.
THIS IS AN INTERVIEWHE
CHILDREN.
THAT WILL BE A LONG, PAINFUL
PROCESS.
SO THIS ADULT SBIEV IS A
POTENTIAL KEY WITNESS.
>> Arthel: AT WHAT POINT WILL
SOME OF THE CHILDREN HAVE
PROVIDED EYEWITNESS ACCOUNTS.
WILL AUTHORITIES TO HAVE SIT
THEM DOWN AND FURTHER QUESTION
THEM AS TO WHAT THEY SAW, WHAT
THEY HEARD.
>> IT'S AN ACTIVE INVESTIGATION
WITH MANY MOVING PARTS.
THERE IS LOT OF THINGS THAT ARE
UNANSWERED AND CERTAIN
UNMITIGATED FACTS.
I WOULD SPECULATE THEY WOULD
BEGIN THAT PAINFUL PROCESS OF
MASSAGING OUT VARIOUS EYEWITNESS
DETAILS FROM THE CHILDREN IN THE
COMING DAYS.
>> Arthel: THEN THERE IS
COMPUTER THAT WAS FOUND AT THE
SHOOTER'S HOME.
WHAT MIGHT BE ON THAT COMPUTER
THAT AUTHORITIES WILL BE LOOKING
FOR?
>> THEY WILL BE INTERESTED IN
ALL ACTIVITY ON THAT COMPUTER.
E-MAILS IN AND OUT.
CONTENT OF E-MAILS, VARIOUS
SITES THAT THE SHOOTER MAY HAVE
VISITED AND WHAT THE RELEVANCE
TO THE BROADER PICTURE.
UNDERSTAND THEY WILL WANT TO
RECONSTRUCT THE LIVES FROM THE
THREE WEAPONS, FROM THE WORK
BENCH UNTIL 9:40 A.M. ON FRIDAY
THE 14th BECAUSE THERE MAY HAVE
BEEN OTHER SHOOTINGS ATTACHED TO
THOSE WEAPONS.
>> Arthel: IS THERE ANY
POSSIBILITY THAT SOMEONE WILL BE
HELD CULPABLE IN TERMS OF PAYING
A CRIMINAL PRICE FOR THIS,
CRIMINAL CHARGES?
>> IT'S DIFFICULT TO SAY.
IT'S AN EVOLVING CASE BUT THE
INITIAL FACTS AS THEY HAVE BEEN
ASCERTAINED SEEM TO SUPPORT THE
SOLE SHOOTER AND SOLE SHOOTER
CULPABILITY.
AT THIS JUNCTURE IT SEEMS LIKE
ADAM LANZA ALONE FROM THE FACTS
WE KNOW.
>> AS AUTHORITIES COLLECT
INFORMATION IN THE COMING DAYS
AND WEEKS AND PERHAPS MONTHS
PERHAPS WE WILL AT SOME POINT
FIND OUT WHY WHICH WILL NOT
CHANGE THAT HORRIFIC EVENT THAT
TOOK PLACE.
I APPRECIATE YOUR ANALYSIS
TODAY.
>> Rick: TOMORROW IS A SCHOOL
DAY AND CALLS FOR STRONGER
SECURITY MEASURES AT OUR
NATION'S SCHOOLS GETTING LOUD
THEY ARE THE WAKE OF THIS
MASSACRE.
SOME EXPERTS SAY THERE ISN'T
MUCH MORE THAT CAN BE DONE TO
IMPROVE CAMPUS SAFETY.
WHERE DO AMERICAN SCHOOLS STAND
RIGHT NOW?
THE PRESIDENT OF THE NATIONAL
SAFETY AND SECURITY
ADMINISTRATION WEIGHS IN NEXT.
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
>>.
>> Arthel: THE CONNECTICUT
TRAGEDY THRUST SCHOOL SAFETY
BACK IN THE NATIONAL SPOTLIGHT.
USING SECURITY MEASURES, CHECK
INS AND METAL DETECTORS.
WHAT CAN WE DO TO MAKE SURE THAT
OUR SCHOOLS ARE SAFE.
JOINING US IS KEN TRUMP.
YOU ARE A CONSULTANT FOR SCHOOLS
AND YOU HELP THEM DEVICE PLANS
TO KEEP SCHOOLS SAFE.
I'M GOING DROP MY KINDERGARTENER
OFF TO SCHOOL TOMORROW MORNING
AND I'M GOING TO WALK AWAY AND
I'M GOING TO THINK IS THAT
SCHOOL SAFE.
HOW CAN WE MAKE SURE?
>> WELL, PARENTS DEFINITELY NEED
TO SEND THEIR KIDS TO SCHOOL
TOMORROW.
SCHOOL WILL BE THE SAFEST PLACE
THEY CAN BE BUT SIX YEARS DOWN
THE ROAD WE HOPE WE'RE HAVING
THE WHOLE CONVERSATION THAT
WE'RE HAVING TODAY.
ONE OF THOSE THINGS WE DON'T
NEED TO CREATE A WHOLE NEW
PLAYBOOK WITH NEW PRACTICES AND
PROCEDURES TEACHING KIDS TO
ATTACK ARMED INTRUDERS.
FOCUS ON THE FUNDAMENTALS AND
HAVE CRISIS TEAMS, SUPPORT OUR
SCHOOL RESOURCE OFFICERS AND
POLICE OFFICERS AND LOOK AT
THOSE PROGRAMS.
LOOK AT THE EXPERIENCE AFTER
COLUMBINE ON BUILDING
RELATIONSHIPS WITH STUDENTS TO
PREVENT VIOLENCE.
MAKING SURE SCHOOLS ARE WORKING
WITH POLICE AND WHOLE LIST OF
OTHER THINGS.
A LOT OF THINGS WE NEED TO DO WE
NEED A LITTLE BIT MORE MONEY.
A LOT OF SCHOOL SAFETY FUNDS
HAVE BEEN CUT AND WE NEED MOST
OF ALL TO SPEND MORE TIME
WORKING ON THIS.
>> Rick: I THINK THERE WOULD BE
A GREATER APPETITE OR DISCUSSION
ABOUT PUT SOMETHING MONEY BACK
INTO THE SYSTEM FOR SECURITY
NEEDS.
I TALKED TO A GUEST YESTERDAY,
KEN, WHO TOLD ME THAT ALL THESE
SHOOTINGS TAKE PLACE IN WHAT
THEY CALL GUN FREE ZONES.
IF TEACHERS WERE ARMED AND BRAVE
PRINCIPAL HAD BEEN ARMED SHE
MIGHT HAVE BEEN ABLE TO STOP
THIS.
WHAT ARE YOUR THOUGHTS ON THAT?
>> I STRONGLY BASED SCHOOL BASED
POLICE OFFICERS.
OUR LAW OFFICERS WERE TRAINED TO
WITH FIREARMS.
I THINK TEACHERS WANT TO BE
ARMED WITH TEXTBOOKS IN THE
SCHOOLS TO TEACH.
OFFICERS HAVE PREVENTED MANY
MORE TRAGEDIES THAN WHAT WE SAW
IN NEWTOWN LAST WEEK BUT WE ALSO
NEED AND SOMETIMES TO INTERVENE.
>> Rick: I HAVE TO JUMP IN.
WE APPRECIATE YOU JOINING US.
POLICE ARE HOLDING ANOTHER PRESS
CONFERENCE.
THAT IS LIEUTENANT VANCE.
LET'S LISTEN.
>> IT'S IDENTIFIED AS NANCY
LANZA.
HER BIRTH DATED IS SEPTEMBER 6,
1960.
HER DEATH HAS BEEN RULED AS
HOMICIDE.
MALE SUSPECT AT SANDY HOOK AS
BEEN POSITIVELY IDENTIFIED AS
ADAM LANZA.
HIS CAUSE OF DEATH IS GUNSHOT
WOUNDS AND HIS DEATH HAS BEEN
RULED AS SUICIDE.
THERE HAVE BEEN QUESTIONS ABOUT
WEAPONRY.
SOME OF THE INFORMATION THAT CAN
BE RELEASED AT THIS TIME.
THE WEAPON THAT WAS UTILIZED
MOST OF THE TIME DURING THIS
HORRIFIC CRIME WAS IDENTIFIED AS
BUSHMASTER AR-15 ASSAULT WEAPON.
THE SUBJECT HAD IN HIS PEAFGS
GLOCK TEN MILLIMETER, SIX MILL
MERELY AND .9 MILLIMETER, ALL
HAVE MULTIPLE MAGAZINES.
FOURTH WEAPON WAS A SHOTGUN THAT
WAS RECOVERED FROM THE SUSPECT'S
VEHICLE THAT WAS PARKED OUTSIDE
OF THE SCHOOL.
THAT WEAPONRY IS GOING, AS I
SAID, GOING TO BE COMPLETELY
EXAMINED.
IT WILL BE HISTORICALLY SEARCHED
TO ATTEMPT TO DETERMINE EVERY
PATH THOSE WEAPONS TOOK SINCE
THEY WERE MANUFACTURED, AS MUCH
INFORMATION AS POSSIBLE WE CAN
OBTAIN RELATIVE TO EACH AND
EVERY WEAPON.
WHAT WE STATED THIS MORNING, BUT
ANYONE THAT HARASSES, THREATENS
OR INTIMIDATES OR INTERFERES
WITH THE INVESTIGATION, USING
SOCIAL MEDIA OF ANY TYPE
RELATIVE TO THIS HORRIFIC CRIME
WILL BE FULLY INVESTIGATED AND
FULLY PROSECUTED TO THE EXTENT
OF THE LAW.
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT THAT LAST.
INCLUDES, IN PERSONAL CONTACT
BUT ALSO CONTACT ON THE INTERNET
SOCIAL MEDIA, TELEPHONE OR ANY
OTHER MEANS OF COMMUNICATION.
WE AGAIN ARE ASKING AND
IMPLORING MEMBERS OF THE MEDIA
TO PLEASE RESPECT THE FAMILIES'
PRIVACY.
WE ARE CONTINUING TO STAFF A
LINE OF COMMUNICATION TO ASSIST
ALL FAMILIES, ALL 26 FAMILIES
AND WE WILL DO SO FOR THE
COLONEL AND STATE POLICE
INDEFINITELY.
I'LL TAKE A COUPLE OF QUESTIONS.
AGAIN, UNDERSTANDING THAT THERE
ARE CERTAIN THINGS WE STILL
CANNOT ANSWER AND CANNOT
DISCUSS.
THERE WAS IN FACT A THREAT AT
THE ST. ROSE CHURCH HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
THE CHURCH AND EVERYTHING IS
TAKEN EXTREMELY SERIOUSLY.
THE CHURCH WAS EVACUATED AS A
PRECAUTION.
IT WAS THOROUGHLY SEARCHED.
WE INITIATED A CRIMINAL
INVESTIGATION.
I HAVE NO FURTHER DETAILS.
I DON'T KNOW THE CONTENT OF THE
THREAT.
SUFFICE IT TO SAY WE TREAT THESE
INSTANCES AS VERSUS CRIMES.
AND IF PERPETRATOR IS IDENTIFIED
THAT INDIVIDUAL WILL BE
PROSECUTED TO THE FULL EXTENT OF
THE LAW.
>> THE PHONE CALLS?
>> THAT IS AS MUCH INFORMATION
AS I HAVE.
>> DID HE USE HANDGUNS AT ALL.
>> I DO NOT KNOW THE WEAPON THAT
NANCY WAS SHOT WITH.
I DON'T KNOW THAT.
BUSHMASTER WAS USED AS EXPLAINED
YESTERDAY IN THE SCHOOL IN ITS
ENTIRETY AND HEALING WAS USED TO
TAKE HIS OWN LIFE.
IT'S A DIRECTORY OF THE SHOTS,
ALL OF THE AMMUNITION USED IN
THIS HORRIFIC CRIME WILL BE
EXAMINED AND THOROUGHLY REPORTED
IN THE REPORT.
I DON'T HAVE THAT INFORMATION TO
BE ABLE TO SPECIAL LATE.
HIGH CAPACITY, MULTIPLE HIGH
CAPACITY MAGAZINES.
APPROXIMATELY 30 ROUNDS PER
MAGAZINE.
HUNDREDS OF BULLETS, YES.
>> WAS IT A RIFLE OR HANDGUN.
>> HIGH CAPACITY MAGAZINE FOR
THE RIFLE AND MULTIPLE MAGAZINES
FOR THE RIFLE AND MULTIPLE
MAGAZINES FOR BOTH HANDGUNS.
I DON'T WANT TO STATE THAT.
I'M SURE THEY DID EVERYTHING
THEY COULD.
I DON'T WANT TO GET INTO THAT
SPECIFIC DETAIL AT THIS TIME.
AGAIN, MOTIVE AS I DISCUSSED
EARLIER, THAT WILL COME AS WE
FINISH THE INVESTIGATION.
WE CAN'T PIECEMEAL IT.
WE DON'T HAVE A SPECIFIC REASON
WE CAN STAND HERE AND SAY THIS
OCCURRED.
WE WILL AND WE ARE SEARCHING
DILIGENTLY AND NONSTOP TO ANSWER
THAT QUESTION.
THE TIME SHRINE BEING
ESTABLISHED BY INVESTIGATORS.
THAT IS THE BEST I CAN DO WITH
THAT.
GO AHEAD.
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
WE'RE STILL WORKING WITH THE
SUPERINTENDENT OF SCHOOLS TO DO
WHAT IS BEST.
OBVIOUSLY IT'S AN EMOTIONAL
TIME.
THE PLAN RIGHT NOW IS STILL UP
IN THE AIR.
THEY ARE FINALIZE GO THE PLANS
AND WE'LL GET THAT INFORMATION
OUT AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
AS I SAID IT'S STILL TO BE
DETERMINED.
>> DO WE KNOW HOW MANY SHOTS
WERE FIRED?
>> THAT IS IMPOSSIBLE TO SAY.
WE DO KNOW HOW MANY ROUNDS WE
RECOVERED.
WE DO KNOW HOW MANY SHELL
CASINGS WE RECOVERED BUT I DON'T
HAVE THAT INFORMATION TO GIVE
OUT.
I WOULD BE SPECULATING AND
GUESSING.
>> HOW MANY MAGAZINES?
>> AGAIN THAT IS INFORMATION
THAT I'M NOT PRIVY TO.
I DON'T HAVE THAT TO GIVE YOU.
MANY, MANY, HUNDREDS.
YES, SIR, CORRECT.
SIR?
I DON'T KNOW THAT.
THE QUESTION IS HE IS COMING TO
THE TOWN OF NEWTOWN, THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES.
AGAIN, WE DON'T DISCUSS SECURITY
FOR THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES.
SUFFICE IT TO SAY SIGNIFICANT
SECURITY WILL BE IN PLACE.
NO, SIR.
NO TIME FRAME HAS BEEN
DETERMINED.
>> ARE YOU MAKING PROGRESS IN
DETERMINING....
>> WE'RE PLEASED WITH THE WORK
THAT WE'RE MAKING.
WE'RE PLEASED WITH THE PROGRESS
WE'RE MAKING.
THIS TEED US ON PROCESS, IT WILL
TAKE MANY, MANY MAN-HOURS TO PUT
THIS PICTURE TOGETHER.
THE MINUTE WE HAVE IT, OUR
OBJECTIVE IS TO MAKE SURE THAT
YOU AND MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC
RECEIVE THAT INFORMATION AS
QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE.
WE HAVE A MOTIVE OR MOTIVE WE
ARE PREPARED TO DISCUSS, THAT
CANNOT HAPPEN.
WE JUST DON'T HAVE THAT.
I WOULD AGAIN, I DON'T WANT TO
DISCUSS THE CRIME SCENE AT ALL.
WE DID SEIZE A GREAT DEAL OF
EVIDENCE.
OUR DETECTIVES HAVE EXECUTED
NUMEROUS SEARCH WARRANTS IN THIS
CASE.
WE DO NOT DETAIL THE C OF
WHAT WE SEIZE IN ANY CRIMINAL
INVESTIGATION.
I CAN TOLL YOU WE WERE
SUCCESSFUL IN SEIZE AGO GREAT
DEAL OF INFORMATION.
ALL THAT EVIDENCE NEEDS TO BE
ANALYZED AND IT WILL BE WHETHER
IN OUR FORENSIC LABORATORY OR
SPECIALISTS AS TIME GOES ON.
WE ANTICIPATE THIS IS GOING TO
BE THE LAST DISCUSSION TODAY.
WITH THE PRESIDENT COMING IN WE
HAVE A GREAT DEAL ON OUR PLATE.
IF ANYTHING ADDITIONAL SHOULD
SURFACE WE WILL POST IT ON THE
STATE POLICE WEBSITE BUT WE DO
NOT ANTICIPATE ANYTHING THAT
SHOULD ARISE.
IF IT ARISES, CHECK ON OUR
WEBSITE ON A REGULAR BASIS.
WE WILL BE BACK HERE TOMORROW
MORNING, WE'LL SHOOT FOR 9:00.
WE WANT TOO KEEP YOU UPDATED AS
MUCH AS WE POSSIBLY CAN.
BY TOMORROW MORNING, WE'LL HAVE
AN IDEA