>> AND THE LIBERAL MEDIA SAID
I FACRIICATED.
BE SKEPTICAL OF THE MEDIA.
MANY OF THEM ARE NOT IN THE
BUSINESS WAS TELLING THE
TRUTH.
CHECK OUT THE FOX NUSE FACTOR.
AND WE WOULD LIKE YOU TO SPOUT
OUT ANYWHERE IN THE WORLD.
IT IS GREAT NEW WORD.
NO PILL POLL.
NO ONE KNOWS WHAT IT MEANT.
THANKS FOR WATCHING US
TONIGHT.
THE SPIN STOPS RIGHT HERE AND
WE ARE LOOKING OUT FOR YOU.
>> THIS IS IT A NOXFOX NEWS
AALL RIGHT.
WE LEARNED FROM CONNECTICUT
POLICE INVESTIGATORS FOUND
SIGNIFICANT EVIDENCE WHERE DAY
BEGAN IN ADAM LANZA'S HOME.
BETWEEN HIS COMMUTER AND CELL
PHONE A MOTIVE WILL BE
EVIDENT.
THE FIRST TWO VICTIMS WERE
HELD TODAY FOR SIX YEAR OLD
NOAH PENZAR.
AND JACK.
MOLLY LINE HAS THE LATEST ON
THE INVESTIGATION FROM NEWTON
TONIGHT.
WHAT ARE YOU LEARNING TONIGHT?
>> I HAD A CHANCE TO SPEAK
WITH THE PEOPLE WHO NANCY
LANZA, THE MOTHER .
SHOOTER AND THEY CONSIDERED
HER A FREE.
SHE HUNG OUT THE PUB CALLED MY
PLACE AND SHE WAS A NORMAL
WOMAN.
THERE IS WHITE SHE WAS
INTERESTED IN GUNS AND
SHOOTING, IT WAS NOT A BIG
PART OF HER PERSONALITY.
>> SHE'S DESCRIBED AS SOME
KIND MUCH A GUN YOU KNOW
ENTHUSIAST OR GUN NUT
SURVIVALIST AND THINGS THAT I
HEARD AND THAT IS NOT THE
NANCY I KNOW.
I KNOW SHE HAS GUNS AND SHE
ENJOYING TARGET SHOOTING AND
THAT'S ALL I KNOW.
IT IS NOT THE PRIMARY HOBBY.
>> AND ONE OF THE MOST
INTERESTING THINGS WE LEARNED
WAS THROUGH THE MEDICAL AGENCY
SAYING IT WAS TRUE MOTHER AND
SON WENT TO THE GUN RANGES
TOGETHER BUT THEY COULDN'T
FIND EVIDENCE THAT THE SHOOTER
HAD BEEN TO A GUN RANGE.
SOME OF NANCY LANZA'S FRIENDS
SAID SHE WAS A TROUBLED MOTHER
IN TRYING TO FIND HELP FOR HER
SON AND HAVING DIFFICULTY IN
LIFE FOR DOING THAT.
HE ATTENDED COMMUNITY COLLEGE
NEARBY AND HANDEMED COLLEGE
COURSES CIVIL OF THE FREPPEDS
SAID HE WAS LOOKING INTO
POSSIBLY GOING TO COLLEGE AND
SHE WOULD BE WILLING TO PULL
UP ROOTS AND LEAVE NEW TOWN TO
GO TO A NEWTOWN IF HE FOUND A
PLACE TO GO TO COLLEGE.
SHE WAS A DEVOTED MOTHER.
>> THANK YOU, MOLLY.
>> WE HAVE THREE DAY TO
REFLECT ON THE EVENTS IN
NEWTOWN, ON FRIDAY.
20 CHILDREN AGES 6 AND 7, AND
SIX ADULTINGS WERE GUNNED DOWN
AND THEY WERE BY ALL ACCOUNTS
WONDERFUL PEOPLE WHO WERE
HERORIC IN DEATH AS THEY GAVE
THEIR LIVES WHO SERVED THE
CHILDREN THAT ARE IN THEIR
CARE.
THERE ARE NO WORDS THAT CAN
RELIEVE THE ORCH WHELMING PAIN
AND SORROW THAT THE FAMILY AND
VICTIMS ARE FEELING NOW AND
THAT WILL STAY WITH THEM FOR
DAYS AND WEEKS AND MONTHS TO
COME.
>> WE ARE TALKING ABOUT GRIEF
BEYOND MESSAGE.
THIS IS WHAT EVIL DOES.
AND WE ARE PRAYING FOR THE
FAMILIES SAD LIE POLITICS
INCLUDED IN THE TRAGEDY.
AND AUTOMATIC FROM THE MINUTE
IT OCCURRED NOW IT IS OUR JOB
TO ADD WHATEVER PERSPECTIVE WE
CAN TO THE DEBATE.
AND THE PREDICTABLE MEDIA AND
MANTRA AGAINST GUNS BEGAN THEY
CALLED ON THE PRESIDENT TO
EXPLOIT THE MURDERS AND HE
SAID THAT WITHOUT SPECTACULARS
OF WHAT HAPPENED.
AND IN JUMPS HOLLYWOOD AND
LEFT POLITICIANS AND THE
PRESIDENT.
WHY WERE THESE SAME PEOPLE,
MINE OF THEM SIABOUT THE FAST
AND FURIOUS SCANDAL?
WHY DO POLITICIAN HOLLYWOOD
STARS, ALL HAVE ARMED SECURITY
FOR THEMSELVES?
WHY?
I HAVE YET TO HEAR ONE
PROPOSAL TO PREVENT THIS
TRAGEDY FROM NEWTOWN FROM
HAPPENING.
DOES IT INCLUDE PARENTING
ISSUES AND DRAMATIC RISE IN
MEDICATION OR INCLUDE VILEP
MOVIES AND TV CULTURE OBSESSED
WITH VIOLENCEMENT CAN WE
DISCUSS BRIPPINGING GOOD AND
10 COMMAND AMS BACK IN THE
CLASSROOM?
WE SHOULD ACT INTELLIGENTLY
AND RELY ON FACTS AND APPROACH
THE MASSACRE IN A FOCUSED AND
IN'S CALM AND REASONABLE WAY
WE SHOULD ACT IN A WAY THOO
BRINGS US TO THE NEWTOWN
MASSACRE AND THE ISSUE OF GUN
CONTROL.
LIBERALS IN THE MEDIA AND SAFE
TO SAY PRESIDENT OBAMA AS WELL
BASED ON HIS MEMORIAL
COMMENTS.
IS USING IT TO ADD HIS VOICE.
DON LENIN ON A ANTI-RANT.
WE NEED TO GET GUNS AND
WEAPONS OFF OF THE STREET AND
ONLY AVAILABLE TO POLICE
OFFICERS AND AL-QAIDA AND.
AND NOT HUNT ELEMENTARY
CHILDREN.
>> WHY WOULD ANYONE OWN A
ASSAULT RIFLE TEMPERATURE IS
THE CONFISCATION OF THE
WEAPONS THAT COUNSELS AND WILL
IMPACTMENT PBS, YOUR TAX DID
AT WORK.
>> IT IS EASIER TO BUY AN
AUTOMATIC WEAPON THAN RENT AN
AUTOMOBILE.
YOU CAN'T B ONE WITHOUT A
SPECIAL LICENSE FROM THE
BUREAU OF TOBEACCO.
WE'LL SEE AN AVALANCHE OF
COMMENTS.
WE ARE FACING A LIBERAL
IDEOLOGY THAT WANTS TO UNDO
THE SECOND AMENDMENT AND THEY
ARE EAGER TO ADVANCE THEIR
CAUSE.
WHAT IS IT FOR US.
THREE DAYS AFTER THE NEWTOWN
TRAGEDY.
THINK ABOUT WE ACT AND RESIST
THE TEMPTATION.
AND JAMMING THROUGH
LEGISLATION IN ORDER TO DO
SOMETHING IF WE DO, DO
SOMETHING LET'S BE SMART ABOUT
IT AND PURSUE POLICILESS THAT
WORK ASK NOT MAKE THE PEOPLE
ON THE LEFT FEEL BETTER.
AND WE MIGHT SAVE INNOCENT
LIVES.
IF THE LEFT RESPECTS THE
CONSTITUTIONAL ROITS PERHAPS
THEY'LL LOOK AT SEARCHING OUR
POLICY RELATED TO MENTAL
HEALTH AND SCHOOL SECURITY.
IF THEY DON'T THEY WILL BE
EXPOSED FOR CONCLUDING WHAT IS
HAPPENING.
THEY ARE ADVANCING FOR AGENDA.
AND THAT WOULD BE SICKENING.
HERE IS HUGH HEWET AND MONICA
CROWLEY JERRY NADLER.
WE'LL EXPLOIT IT WITHIN HOURS,
THEY ARE RACING TO BLAME GUNS
AND KNEW NOTHING.
>> DOESN'T WHAT THE ACTUL
FACTS OR DEOF THE I JUST KNEW
HERE WE GO AGAIN AND THEY DO
IT EVERY SINGLE TIME THERE IS
A TRAG DOE INVOLVING A GUN.
THEY FOCUS ON THE WEAPON THAN
THE PRERPITATOR AND DIRECT THE
MORAL TO THAT AND IT IS ABOUT
THE IDEOLOGY AND STRIPPING
LAW-ABIDING AMERICAN CITIZENS
FROM THE LEGAL RIGHT TO HAVE A
GUN.
>> I AM LOOKING AT PARENTING
ISSUES.
WHY WOULD YOU HAVE A GUN IN
THE HOME WITH A KID THAT IS
MENTALLY ILL AND BURNING
HIMSELF.
WHY WOULD THERE BE ANY ACCESS
IF WE HAVE A QUESTION IN MIRK.
>> ON FRIDAY'S PROGRAM I HAD
THE ARCH BISHIP OF
PHILADELPHIA AND HE TALKED
ABOUT METROPOLITANAL HEALTH
ISSUES IN THE UNITED STATES.
WE LOOK AT AURORA AND VIRGINIA
TECH.
EACH OF THE KILL ARES
PROFOUNDLY MENTALLY UNSTABLE.
YOU GUN THERE AND TALK ABOUT
WHAT YOU DO WITH THAT.
THERE IS AN AMAZING POST BY A
SOCCER MOM WHO DEEDS WITH A
DOUBLED PERSON.
IT IS GENERATED QUESTIONS FROM
THOUSANDS OF AMERICANS WITH
TROUBLED YOUNG PERSON'S.
THEY ARE MISSING AN
OPPORTUNITY TO SAY THIS IS NOT
EASY.
WHAT DO WE DO ABOUT THE
PEOPLE?
THEY ARE MAKING WHAT IT IS
NOT.
>> CAN IT INCLUDE PARENTING
ISSUES AND MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES MEDICATION DISTRIBUTION
TO CHILDREN AND WE HAVE SEEN
IT WITH THE MEDICINES AND
VIOLENT MOVIES AND VIDEO GAMES
AND GOD REMOUVED FROM THE
CLASSROOM .
>> EVERY TIME THIS HAPPENS,
THE RUMAN MIND TRIES TO LOOK
FOR THE REASON.
IS IT CULTURE OR VIDEO GAMES.
ON THE LEFT THEY REACH FOR AT
GUN EXPLANATION .
SOMETIMES THE OBVIOUS ANSWER
IS THE CORRECT ONE.
EVIL EXISTS.
A WEEK BEFORE THE MURDERS,
THIS KID TRIED TO BUY A GUN HE
WAS TURNED DOWN AND HE DIDN'T
WANT TO SUBMIT TO THE
BACKGROUND CHECK AND WAITING
PERIOD.
IT IS ABOUT IF WE CAN'T
INTERVENE WITH THESE PEOPLE,
YOU SAW THE PHOTOGRAPH OF THE
GABE GIFFORD SHOOTER.
THEY LOOK NORMAL.
THEY LOOK LIKE SICK
INDIVIDUALS.
THE QUESTION IS TO GET TO THEM
BEFORE IT HAPPENS.
>> I KNOW MOST OF THE PEOPLE
COMMENTING.
I WAS TRAINED IN THE USE OF
FIRE ARMS SINCE I WAS A KID.
MOST OF THE PIME DON'T KNOW
WHAT AN ASSAULT WEAPON AND
AUTOMATIC WEAPONS ARE
AVAILABLE.
BUT THEY GET RID OF ASSAULT
WEAPONS AND THEN IT IS IT
PISTOLS.
IF IT HAPPENS WITH A TIRE IRON
WILL THEY GET RIDE OF THOSE.
>> THEY DON'T KNOW ABOUT THE
SECOND AMENDMENT.
I READ HELLER BEFORE I CAME
ON.
I HEARD SO MUCH STUPID
COMMIPTARY.
AND I WOULD LIKE TO PEOPLE TO
PAUSE.
THIS IS NOT A QUESTION OF WHAT
IN THE CONSTITUTION .
IT IS A QUESTION OF WHAT IS IN
THE INSTITUTION.
THEY CAN MAKE A PROPOSAL BUT
THEY CAN'T REPEAL THE
CONSTITUTION.
I UNDERSTAND THE IRONY AND
TALKING ABOUT THE MEDIA.
BUT GOING BACK TO WHEN
NBCAIRED THAT VIRGINIA TECH
KILLER TAPE, SINCE THEN, THERE
IS A ROLE FOR THE MEDIA TO ACT
RESPONSIBLY.
AND NOT TO COVER AND SEND A
MESSAGE THAT IMMORTALITY
AWAITS ANYONE WHO IS DEED AND
IF THEY PICK UP THE GUN AND
SLAUGHTER INNOCENTS.
WE ARE NOT DOING IT THE RIGHT
WAY.
>> I THANK YOU BOTH FOR A
THOUGHTFUL CONVERSATION AND
SOME OF THE IS RECKLESS AND
IRRESPONSIBLE ANDLY OMITTING
THE PAIN.
>> COMING UP.
INVESTIGATORS WHO PIECE
TOGETHER THE SHOOTER ADAM
LANZA AND TROVE THE TWEPT YEAR
OLD TO COMMIT THEY HADINOUS
CRIME.
HOW IS LAW ENFORCEMENT GETTING
TO THE TRAGEDY.
THAT AND
SOMETIMES LIFE CAN BE WELL,
A LITTLE UNCOMFORTABLE.
BUT WHEN IT'S HARD OR HURTS
TO GO TO THE BATHROOM,
THERE'S DULCOLAX
STOOL SOFTENER.
DULCOLAX STOOL SOFTENER
DOESN'T MAKE YOU GO,
IT JUST MAKES IT
EASIER TO GO.
DULCOLAX STOOL SOFTENER.
MAKE YOURSELF COMFORTABLE.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME R CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
Is bigger than we think ...
Sometimelike the flu.fer from
With aches, fever and chills-
the flu's a really big deal.
So why treat it like
it's a little cold?
There's something
that works differently
than over-the-counter
remedies.
Prescription TAMIFLU attacks
the flu virus at its source.
So don't wait. Call your
doctor right away.
TAMIFLU is prescription
medicine for treating the flu
in adults and children
one year and older
whose flu symptoms started
within the last two days.
Before taking TAMIFLU tell your
doctor if you're pregnant,
nursing. have serious
health conditions,
or take other medicines.
If you develop an allergic
reaction, a severe rash,
or signs of unusual behavior,
stop taking TAMIFLU and call
your doctor immediately.
Children and adolescents in
particular may be at an
increased risk
of seizures, confusion
or abnormal behavior.
The most common
side effects are
mild to moderate nausea
and vomiting.
The flu comes on fast,
so ask your
doctor about TAMIFLU.
Prescription for flu.
>> A NEWTOWN COMMUNITY THE
LOST OF THE YOUNGEST AND MOST
INNOCENT.
POLICE ARE LOOKING AT ADAM
LANZA'S COMPUTER RECOVERY SAID
TO SHED A MOTIVE.
WE ARE LEARNING THAT THE
JOINING ME TO HELP ME EXPLAIN
THE LAW ENFORCEMENT WILL GET
TO THE BOTTOM OF THE
INVESTIGATION.
MARK FURMAN .
WHAT COULD THEY FIND, MARK .
I KNOW EVERYONE IS TRYING TO
RACE TO CONCLUSIONS AND THE
GUN.
AND WHAT WILL THE
INVESTIGATORS LOOK FOR?
>> WELL SEAN, THEY HAVE
ALREADY PROCESSED THE SCENE.
THEY KNOW THEY HAD ONE SHOTTER
RESPONSIBLE AT THE SCENE AND
THE WEAPONS USED IN THE SCEEP
AND THEY CONNECTED THEM UP TO
THE INVESTIGATION .
AND NOW TO HOMICIDE OF THE
MORNING IN THE LANSA HOME .
THEY HOPE TO FIPED EVIDENCE
THAT LEADS THEM TO A DIRECTION
AND OR MEENED STET NATHE
RESPECT IT AND IF WE WAS
FLUENCE AND'S HAD'S MENTAL
ISTHEY CHARRLED ANGER AND
RAGE.
PICTURE IS EMORTGAGING A
ACWARD.
AND WAS BEING WOR.
SCHOOL OFFICIALS LOOKED OUT
FOR HIM SO HOE WOULD NOT BE
BULLIED .
WHAT DO WE SAW TO A PERSON
THAT THEY THEMSELVES AND
NOTHING WAS IN THIS CASE.
IN HIPPED SET, WE ARE OKAYING
AT THIS THAT SOMEONE SHOULD
HAVE RUSHED IN AND
INTERREPPED.
AND TO ACTUALLY PUT 71 IN A
PSYCHATOLOGY TOLD FOR 72
HOURS.
THIGH HAD TO TELL YOU WHAT AT
A IT WAS.
AND THE THE PRESIDENTMENT AND
THEY ARIE RENEVED TO REALITY
THEY ARE A HARM TO THEMSELVES
AND ANOTHER.
>> SEAN, I HAVE BEEN TO WELL
AND HEARING IN ON ARE THE.
AND IS TUE BEING THE WILL
GITHER WASTING TIME.
AND WE THAT HE WENT PROLS COME
UP BARF THES SCHOOLS AND RURAL
HOSPITALS AND HOSPITALS AND
PLICES THAT ARE IN HARD
TARGETS AND WHY DON'T WE TAKE
THE SCHOOLS AND EMPLOY THE
SAMUATOR YOU HAVE IN A
MATTHEWS PRESSURE.
>> LET ME USE YOU TO .
L AND HOW OFTEN IN YOUR YEARS
AS A DEFECTIVE THAT THE SIGNS
WERE EVIDENT .
I AM NOT SURE TROYED YOU
WANTED IN A SCENE LIKE THAT.
SHOY DO I RECOVER FROM THAT.
>> THEY ARE NOT GOING TO
RECOVER CANTHEY WILL ALWAYS
OOMER IT.
LYOU REALLY DON'T.
YOU HAVE TO GO THERE IT AND IT
IS NOT YOUR NOB.
>> IS THE WORST WITH THE
OCCUR.
AND NO ONE IS GOING TO AN FROM
THIS MUCH AND TELL THE FERST
RESPOPPEDERS AS THE THERE IS
SPECKULSION AAT THAT POINT'S
MENTAL APPROXIMATE WE HAVE BIG
DEVELOP THE ON THE OTHER THAN
OF THE CLICHE.
HOED A COUNTY DEAL .
LOOK
THE Capital One
Cash Rewards Card
GIVES YOU 1% CASH BACK
ON ALL PURCHASES,
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS.
AND EVERYONE...BUT HER
LIKES 50% MORE CASH.
BUT I'M UPPING MY GAME.
DO YOU WANT A CANDY CANE?
YES!
DO YOU WANT THE PUPPY?
DO YOU WANT A TRICYCLE?
YES!
DO YOU WANT
50 PERCENT MORE CASH?
NO!
♪
FESTIVE.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE Capital One
Cash Rewards Card
GIVES YOU
1% CASH BACK
ON EVERY
PURCHASE
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS
ON THE CASH YOU EARN.
IT'S THE CARD FOR PEOPLE
WHO LIKE MORE CASH.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
BY SHOWING YOU
THE APARTMENT BUILDING
WHERE THE FIRE WAS.
WHEN THINGS LIKE THIS HAPPEN,
I THINK YOU FIND
A NEW PERSPECTIVE ON LIFE.
RED CROSS PUT US IN A HOTEL
SO WE WERE ABLE
TO STAY TOGETHER.
WE'RE STRONG
AND IF WE OVERCAME THAT
OR IF WE CAN OVERCOME THAT...
WE CAN OVERCOME ANYTHING.
[ SNIFFLES ]
♪
>> WELCOME BACK TO HANNITY.
PARENTS DAMAGE HOW DEVASTATING
IT WOULD BE IT BE A PARENT OF
THOSE KIDS KILLED.
THERE IS OTHER PARTNERSHIPS
THAT HAPPENING ABOUT BEING A
MURDERER.
THE MOTHER DESCRIBED THE
HARDSHIPS RACING HIM WITH A
TOIRE STORESTER.
I AM JAMES HOIMS MOTHER.
AND WHEY WE HAVE WEASEY BAYS
THEIR AND TO UNDERSTAND HOW A
MIPTAL ILLNESS COULD HAVE
CONTRACTED WE HAVE DR. RUSKIN
AND DR. MICHAEL STOPE IN
COLUMBIA WE HEARD THE MOTHER
VOTED AS SAYING, I CONTROL HIM
AND HE'S GETTING WORSE AND
EVERYONE KNEW HE WAS TROUBLED
BUT HE WAS SMART AND A LOT OF
SOCIALS; IS THAT TRUE KIDS CAN
BURN THEMSELVES AND NOT FEEL
BAD.
IT SEEMS LIKE A LOT OF
THIPPINGS MISSED .
>> YES, THERE ARE CHILDREN AND
ADULTS THAT DO INDEED HAVE
THAT SYMPTOM.
BUT WE CAN'T SPECULATE WE
DON'T KNOW IF WE DON'T HAVE
ENOUGH DETAILS AND TO
DIAGNOSE.
IT IS DANGEROUS FOR US AS A
CULTURE BECAUSE WE ARE STUCK
IN THAT MIND SET.
THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO ARE SOCIO
PATHS AND NO CONSCIENCE AND NO
SENSE OF RIGHT ASK WRONG AND
MENALLY IL.
>> LUTELY .
>> WHAT ABOUT PEOPLE WHO
CENTER A CONSCIOUS OR SOUL.
HOW UPON DOE WE HEAR PEOPLE
SAY WE SAW THIS COMING?
SNOMIT ALL PEOPLE WITH NO
EMACTY ARE CLASSIC SOCIO PATHS
AND ASBERGERS, DOESN'T MEAN TO
LOOK AT THAT FACE AND KNOW
WHAT THEY ARE FEELING.
THEY ARE NOT DANGEROUS IN THE
WAY THE PSCO PATH .
PECULIARLY IN THE CASE OF
ABAM.
>> HIS MOTHER IS TELLING
PEOPLE THAT SHE UPONS I CAN'T
CONTROL HIM ANYMORE THAT HE'S
GETTING WORSE.
THAT MEANS EVIDENCE MANAGE IS
NOT RIGHT .
>> I HEARD THAT HE HAD
EMOTIONAL OUTBURST BUT I
DIDN'T HEAR IF HE WAS VIOLENT.
>> HE WAS HURTING HIMSELF?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
I AT ANY TIME ARE HAD ABOUT
THAT?
>> THE COMPONENT WITH
ASBERGERS THOUGH .
A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE UPSET HOW
IN THE NEWS WHY TALKING ABOUT
ASBERGERS OR SUM SUM.
THER BANE'RE MANY CHILDREN
WITH ASBERGERS AND THEY REALLY
DO HAVE EMPATHY AND IT IS
PURPOSE TO PUT IT OUT THAT
WHAT WE TO UPON.
THAT THERE WAS A SEEDED
EMOTIONAL AND METROPOLITANAL
DISTURBANCE THAT STEMMED
STARTING FROM CHILD HOOD WITH
THIS MAN.
>> I DON'T WANT TO AFTER THE
MOTHER.
SHE WAS KILLED IN THIS INSAT
THE PRESENT TIME.
AND A IF YOU HAVE SOMEONE WITH
A MENTAL OPINION THOSE SHOULD
BE MANAGE MISDEMEANORMENT NWHY
HEAR ABOUT ARE WEWE ARE
LEARNING IN A LOT OF CASES
THRATHEY ARE ON EDUCATION .
MOST POEM ARE TALKING TO GUNS
THAN WHAT WE ARE TREATING THE
PIECE.
>> IF CHILD IS SHOWING
EMOTIONAL DISTURBANCE AND
MOVATURANCE.
LOOT UP THE DEPUN AND YOUR CAN
NOT BEEN.
I CAN PUT YOU ON THE TELL MY
DEPIPPEDS ARE.
AND YOU WILL NOT AND I DON'T
HAPPENED IT.
IT NRIGHT.
MEDICATION .
NI AM REQUESTS THE DOCTOR A
QUESTION .
>> ABSOLUTE LOW.
>> IF SHE DID GET HIM TO TALK
WITH HE HERE.
PERHAPS NOT IN THE LAST SEVEN
O'CLOCKS.
THE HIGH KNEW ABOUT THE GUPS
BUT NOT NECESSARILY GOING TO
KIT IT I CARRIED A GUN HALF OF
MY LIFE AND I AM FAMILIAR WITH
FIRE ARMS AND I AMING MORE
ABOUT FIRE SAFETY.
>> I AND I DON'T THINK SHE
OUGHT TO BE A GUN CONTROLLER.
IN ORDER TO HERFS YESTERDAY
FROM LIGHT .
NHE NOTTED SAN EYE VILEPT YES,
YOU RIKE TO USE OF THE WOOTER?
>>IP THAPPING YOU FOR YOUR
INSIGHT.
>> WHO GLETS THE ALL RIGHT OF
MOST POSEDENT .
>> AND THE THAT YOU I TO SARE
THE WELL THE SOURCES ARE
SAYING WE MAY BE CLOSE.
WOE
It's hard to see opportunity
in today's challenging
environment.
Unless you have the right
perspective.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
has the vision
and experience to look beyond
the obvious.
We'll uncover opportunities,
find hidden risk,
and make success a reality.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
TRUST DURACELL TO POWER
THEIR DONATED TOYS?
DURALOCK POWER PRESERVE.
IT LOCKS IN POWER
FOR UP TO 10 YEARS IN STORAGE.
GUARANTEED.
DURACELL WITH DURALOCK.
TRUSTED EVERYWHERE.
>> WE ARE LEARNING THAT HOUSE
SPEAKER BOEHNER AND PRESIDENT
OBAMA ARE GETTING TO A DEAL.
WE ARE LEARNING THAT THE
PRESIDENT PRESENTED A COUNTER
OFF TO BIGGEST BOEHNER.
IT IS 1.2 TRILLION IN TAX
IBCREASES FOR THOSE EARNING
$400,000 OR MORE A YEAR AND A
TWO-YEAR DEBT CEILING INCREASE
AND ANEND TO SEQUESTRATION
SPENDING CUTS AND SAID THAT
(BOMBING NOISE) AND HIS OFFICE
IS A STEP IN THE RIGHT
DIRECTION .
HOAR IS THE SARASOLTA SPRINGS
MAYOR WHO SHOULD BE SENATOR OR
MAYBE PRESIDENT.
>> GOOD TO SEE YOU.
>> I SAID THAT SPEAKER BOEHNER
IS DOING A GOOD JOB
NEGOTIATING WITH HIMSELF.
HE'S GIVING UP ON EVERYTHING.
AND THIS IS THE FIRST MOVE AT
ALL FROM THE PRESIDENT.
I DON'T LIKE TWO YEARS OF NOT
DEALING WITH THE DEBT CEILING.
>> TO GIVE IT UP WOULD BE
DEVASTATING.
AND REALLY THE CARDS ARE ALL
WITH THE ADMINISTRATION AND
DEMOCRATS.
>> LOOK, SEAN IT IS IT A PEACE
MEAL SURRENDERS.
HE'S MORE INTEND ON GETTING A
DEAL.
THE PRESIDENT WANTS MORE
STIMULUS SPENDING IN HIS
PROPOSAL AND TAX REVENUE THAN
CUTS MORE IMPORTANTLY AND I
WROTE A PIECE WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU ARE GOING TO HAVE TO RAISE
TAXES AND TAKE THE SHUMER AND
SAY WE WILL GO WITH THAT.
YOU START THE CUTS AND
REMEMBER SIM SIM-- --
SIMPSON-BOMBS.
>> IF THEY GIVE UP ON THE DEBT
LIMIT.
THEY ARE GIVING THIS PRESIDENT
TWO YEARS, A BLANK CHECK.
>> FOR TWO YEARS AND
DEVASTATING.
AND WE HAVE TO REMEMBER WHAT
WE ARE DEALING WITH HERE.
WE DON'T HAVE A REVENUE
PROBLEM.
WE HAVE A SPENDING PROBLEM.
ORDINARY CITIZENS LIKE MYSELF
HAVE TO LIVE WITHIN OUR MEANS.
AND IF WE TAX THE TOP TWO
BRARKETS THAT WILL COST
$700,000 JOBBINGS.
>> WE HAVE LOST EVERY
LEVERAGE.
>> YOU HAVE GIVEN IT AWAY.
>> HE'S GIVING IT AWAY.
REPUBLICANS ARE NOT GOING TO
STAND AS THE CONSERVATIVE
ALTERATIVE VOICE WHAT ARE THEY
THERE FOR UP.
>> HE'S GIVING UP NOTHING.
>> 250,000 TO TRAXING OF --
TAXING PEOPLE WITH 400,000.
>> HERIA GOING TO GET REVENUE
INCREASES NOW HE WENT FROM 800
BILLION AND WANTS A TRIL ONE
FOUR.
AND BOEHNER RAISED IT TO A
TRILLION TWO.
BUT THIS IS ABOUT SPEPPEDING.
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT A TRAGEDY
TO THE CHILDREN.
HE GETS THE AUTHORITY TO JUST
CONTINUE TO TAKE US WHERE HE
WANTS FOR TWO YEARS NO
RESTRAINTS FROM CONGRESS.
WHAT ARE THEY DOING?
>> WE ARE TALKING ABOUT THE
CHILDREN.
>> THIS IS THE FUTUREF MY
GRAND CHILDREN.
>> AND IT IS IT A MORAL ISSUE.
>> THIS IS TRACHING A SPLEDGE
HAMMER TO THE PIGGY BANK.
>> WE HAVE TO LOOK AT THE
BIGGER PICTURE.
WE ARE TRYING TO MAKE PUBLIC
POLICY WITHOUT FORMING A
PUBLIC OPINION.
WE HAVE TO TALK IN A LANGUAGE
THEY HAPPENED.
AND THAT IS GOING TO AFFECT
US.
WE WILL LOOK AND SEE
UNEMPLOYMENT GO UP AND THE
COMMIGOING IN THE TOILET.
>> WHAT DO YOU THINK
APPROXIMATE OR SAY TO THE
REPUBLICANS?
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THEM.
I SAY SURRENDER.
IF THIS IS THE DEAL, THEY HAVE
SURRENTEDERED.
>> YES.
>> THEY HAVE GIVEN UP.
>> WE LIVE IN A COUNTRY, FOR
CRYING OUT LOUD.
WE NEVER HAVE BEEN A COUNTRY
OF FEAR.
NGET A BACK BONE AND BE A
CONSERVATIVE.
>> NOT ONLY FIGHT BUT MAKE THE
CASE TO THE AMERICAN PEOPLE.
ALL THEY DO IS TALK TO EACH
OTHER.
THE PRESIDENT IS TAKING CARE
OF THE MIDDLE CLASS AND
BOEHNER TALKS TO.
>> WE DIDN'T VOTE THEM IN
OFFICE TO RUBBER STAMP OBAMA
CARE.
THEY WANT THE CUTS AND SO BE
THE PARTY ANY'VE ABOUT SAVING
AND STOPPING THE OVERNIGHT
CLIFF.
>> IT IS GOING TIND BADLY.
AND YOU GET HOLD ON TO THE
LEVERAGE YOU HAVE.
>> I HAPPENING THEY WOULD
SHOULD ON FOR THIS PRESIDENT.
>> AND IT IS UPA LATERAL POWER
IT RAISE IT.
NTHE MCCONOLE MECHIVISM.
NHE MAY LOSE EYE SPEECH.
WE GOT TO GO.
AND COME TO TOWN MORE AWN.
>> I WOULD LOVE THAT.
>> COMING UP MAIN STREAM OBAMA
MAJOR MEDIA ANCHOR TAKES HOME
THE PRIZE.
THE WINNER OF THE MOST BIAG.
I IS THE DOWN WITH JOLE
OLSTEIN AND
COPD makes it hard
to breathe,
but with ADVAIR,
I'm breathing better.
So now I can be in
the scene.
ADVAIR is
clinically proven to help
significantly improve
lung function.
Unlike most COPD medications,
ADVAIR contains both an
anti-inflammatory
and a
long-acting bronchodilator
working together to help improve
your lung function all day.
ADVAIR won't
replace fast-acting inhalers
for sudden symptoms
and should not be used more
than twice a day.
People with
COPD taking ADVAIR
may have a higher chance
of pneumonia.
ADVAIR may increase your
risk of osteoporosis
and some eye problems.
Tell your doctor
if you have a heart condition
or high blood pressure before
taking ADVAIR.
If you're still
having difficulty breathing,
ask your doctor if including
ADVAIR could help
improve your lung function.
Get your
first full
prescription
free
and save
on refills
at
ADVAIRcopd.com.
TRY RUNNING FOUR.NING
A RESTAURANT IS HARD,
FORTUNATELY WE'VE GOT INK.
IT GIVES US 5X THE REWARDS
ON OUR INTERNET, PHONE
CHARGES AND CABLE,
PLUS AT OFFICE SUPPLY STORES.
REWARDS WE PUT RIGHT
BACK INTO OUR BUSINESS.
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
WE'VE EVER WANTED TO DO
AND INK HELPS US DO IT.
MAKE YOUR MARK
WITH INK FROM CHASE.
>> EVERY WEEK WE EXPOSE THE
MEDIA AS BLATENT MEDIA BIAS.
THERE IS A YEAR OF THE
NOTABLES AND QUOTABLES SELECT
THE WORST REPORTINGS .
WHO HADLET QUOTE OF THE YEAR
IS THE PRESIDENT OF THE MRC.
>> YEAH .
>> WE HAVE DONE IT 25 YEARS .
>> 25 YEARS AND WE HAVE DONE
IT AND YOU HAVE BEEN A JUDGE
ON IT 20 YEARS AND ALSO THE
HOST OF TEMPERATURE YOU ARE
ONE OF THE PEOPLE RESPONSIBLE
FOR WHAT WE TALK ABOUT.
>> CHRIS MATTHEWSES AND NIGHT
HE WAS E LECTED.
AND HE WAS GLAD SUPER STORM
HIT THEIR LIVES.
>> GOOD WORK FOR HIM GOOD DAY
FOR AMERICA .
I AM SO GLAD WE HAD THRASTORM
LAST WEEK.
IT WAS ONE OF THOSE THINGS
POLITICALLY.
BUT IT BROUGHT IN POLICIES.
>> I AM SO GLAD WE HAD THAT
STORM.
PIME'S HOMES ARE RUINED AND
CHRIS MATTHEWS IS FOR OUT OF HIS
MOUTH.
AND THE CO2 IN RUSH LIM
BAH'SED HAD.
AND HILLARY CLINTON BECOMING A
VIANTOR BECAUSE HER HUSBAND
WAS EYE LOUT.
AND KKKIS THE REPUBLICAN.
>> HE IS JUST RAMBLING
NONSENSICAL NONSENSE.
HE IS MUCH BETTER THAN THIS.
SOMETHING'S HAPPENED TO HIM.
>> YOU DO HAVE THE OBAMA MANIA
WAR.
AND CHRIS WON THAT, TOO OVER
>> THIS GUY HAS DONE
EVERYTHING RIGHT AND PRAISED
HIS FAMILY RIGHT AND IN A
BLIND TEST BECOMES THE HEAD OF
THE REVIEW .
EVERYTHING IS CLEAN AS A
WHISTLE AND NEVER BROKEN A
LAW.
HE'S A PERFECT FATHER AND
HUSBAND AND AMERICAN AND ALL
THEY DO IS TRASH THE GUY.
>> YOU GET THE DRUG USE.
COCAINE.
AND THE CHUM GAIN.
AND GOT THOSE LITTLE THINGS .
>> IF CHRIS MATTHEWS COULD
CARRY BARAK OBAMA'S NEXT CHILD
WANT.
>> OH, MAN, THAT IS COLD.
>> I KNOW, I KNOW.
>> OH,.
>> WE ARE NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR
THINGS PEOPLE SAY ON THE
PROGRAM.
>> IT IS IT BAD.
I MEAN, I USED -- WHEN YOU
MEET HIM HE IS IT A GUY .
>> IY CONVERSATION AND HE WAS
REASONABLE AND HE'S GONE ON TO
THE DARK SIDE OF REALITY ON
THESE THINGS.
EVEN HE DOESN'T BELIEVE WHAT
HE IS A SUGGEST ABOUT BARAK
OBAMA.
>> HE GETS HIMSELF A THRILL.
>> THIS WENT WAY BEYOND THE
LOG.
>> NEW YORK TIMES COMCOLUMIST.
MITT ROMNEY CENTER A SOUL.
HIS CHEST IS A GOLD TICKING.
THIS IS NOT A PERSON.
BUT A ROBOT WHO WILL DO
WHATEVER IT IS TAKES AND TOLD
TOY TO DO.
NTHERE IS EYE LOT OF MEAN
THINGS SAID ABOUT A GOOD MAN.
SELFISH EVIL MEEP CAPTITALIST.
AND A LOT OF DIRTY AIR HAD AND
KILLING GRANDMA .
NI DON'T KNOW IF FOR A FACT.
BUT I BET YOU HE NEVER MET
ROMNY.
AND NEVER TALKED TO THE MAP.
IT IS THE RULES OF JOURNALISM
TODAY.
A CONSERVATIVE SHALL NOT TAKE
IT ABOUT THE LIBERALS >> QUOTE
OF THE YEAR.
NUMBER ONE.
SO WHO IS THE WINNER?
>> WATCH.
>> THE LAND ON WHICH THEY
FORMED THE UNION WAS STOLEN
AND HAPPENEDS ON WHICH THEY
BUILT THIS NATION WAS IPSLAVED
AND THE WOMEN WHO BIRTHED THE
CITIZENS ARE SECOND GLASS.
RAT TIMES WE HAVE TORN AND
STAINED OUR NATION AND ANOTHER
MOMENTS WE WIND AND REPAIRED
IT IT IS IT ALL.
IMPERIALIZE AND GENIDE AND
HOPE THAT OUR BEST DAYS STILL
LIE AHEAD OF US.
>> THAT IS FASCISM.
AND IMPERIALAN AND TAKING ON
THE BURDEN OF BATTLING
TERRORIST?
>> WHEN RONALD REGAN WON THE
IF THE SEE.
HE DEFEATED THE BLAME AMERICA
CROWD.
>> THE BLAME AMERICA CROWD
CAME BACK BUT FOR MORE MILL AT
THAT POINT.
AND IT IS SCRIBED TO AMERICAN
THAT IS NOT TRUE.
WE STOPPED IT AND WHICH WE
LOOK NO REALISTIC, THESE ARE
THE PEOPLE WHO ARE THAT.
>> SAD, AND WORK YOU ARE
DOING.
IN THE WAKE OF FRIDAY'S
TRAGEDY AND THE HOLIDAYS
AHEAD.
I SAT DOWN WITH JOLE OLSTEIN
WITH MUCH NODED WORDS A A A A A
I ALWAYS WAIT
UNTIL THE LAST MINUTE.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME R CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
>> THERE IS IT NO ANSWER TO
WHY IT HAPPENED.
WE NEED TO BE A CAN HAVE THE
AND CONSOLATION.
THESE PARENTS LOST THEIR
HEARTS AND TRY TO REACH OUT
AND SHOW THEM CARE AND CONCERN
IS OUR TOP PRIORITY.
>> THAT WAS MONSIGNOR ROBERT
WEISS.
HE IS AMONG THE MANY CLERGY
MEMBERS THAT THAT COMMUNITY
WILL TURN TO AS THEY SEARCH
FOR ANSWERS AND ONE WEEK UNTIL
CHRISTMAS.
THAT TACK IS PAINFUL AND
JOINING ME ABOUT THE ROLE OF
FAITH.
JOLE AND VICTORIA OLSTEEN OF
THE LAKEWOOD CHURCH IN
HOUSTON.
HOW ARE YOU DOING .
>> GREAT.
THANK YOU GOOD TO BE HERE.
>> YOU CAN'T WRITE WORDS TO
HELP PARENTS WHO LOSE KIDS
LIKE THAT.
NOTHING YOU COULD SAY TO ME
THAT WOULD HELP ME.
>> IT HAS TO BE THE GRACE OF
GOD TO GET YOU THROUGH.
THAT'S WHAT WE DEAL WITH
SITUATIONS LIKE THAT IN A BIG
CHURCH YOU FEEL AT A LOSS.
ALL I CAN TELL YOU IS GOD HAS
YOU IN THE PALM OF THE
HAPPENED.
AND SOME OF THE FAMILIES FEEL
THE PEACE.
IT IS SAD AND TRAGIC, BUT HAS
A WAY OF GITING YOU THROUGH
THESE THINGS .
>> IT IS GOING TO TAKE A LOT
OF TIME.
IT IS A WEEK BEFORE CHRISTMAS
AND WORDS CAN'T COMPLESS.
BUT JUST BEING THERE.
YOU DON'T NEED TO STAY MANAGE
AND HAVING PEOPLE WHO LOVE YOU
AND KNOWING SUPPOSE.
>> I DON'T THINK I WOULD BE
FORGIVING AS A CHRISTIAN.
I CAN'T IMAGINE THIS PAIN.
YOU LOSE YOUR CHILD AND
SOMEONE KILLS YOUR KID.
I KNOW WHAT JESUS DID ON THE
CROSS, BUT I AM NOT JESUS AS
AWE LOT OF PEOPLE KNOW.
I AM SHOWERS, I DON'T KNOW HOW
YOU DO THAT.
>> SEAN, YOU NEVER WERE IN
THUATION AND YOU DON'T HAVE
THE GRACE AND FATHOM THAT.
A COUPLE OF PEOPLE ARED ARE
YOU ANGRY.
ASK ONE SAID WE HAVEN'T WE ARE
JUST TOO SAD.
IF I WOULD ANGRY, TOO.
I WOULD LOSE MY MIND.
THERE ARE PHASES OF THE ANGER
AND GRIEF AND YOU DEALT WITH
PARENTS THAT LOST THEIR KIDS.
>> IT IS UNNATURAL.
YOU DON'T EXPECT TO LOSE YOUR
CHILD .
YOU GO THROUGH THE PAIN.
AND THE THING YOU DO IS GET
STUCK IN ONE AREA.
HOPEFULLY THEY WILL FIPED THE
SUPPORT.
AND WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT IT,
IF THAT CHILD COULD COME BACK.
THEY WOULD NOT WANT THAT CHILD
STUCK.
MY ENCOURAGEMENT TO THE
PARENTS IS IT IS HARD AND
COULD TAKE YEARS AND YEARS AND
IF YOU WANT TO GET CLOSE TO
YOUR CHILD.
GET CLOSE TO GOD.
YOUR CHILD IS WITH GROD GOD.
>> YOU MARRIED UP.
AND THAT IS -- I GAVE YOU A
HARD TIME.
YOU ARE TILL WITH HIM.
>> I HAVE KNOWN YOU 25 YEARS.
>> AND I CAN GET AWAY WITH
BEING A PAIN IN THE NECK.
>> WHAT IS THE HARDEST THING
TO COUNSEL.
THIS AND THE INDICATING OF A
CHILD OR TEENAGER KILLED IN A
AUTOMOBILE ACCIDENTS.
THERE ARE NO WORDS TO SAY.
MOURN WITH THOSE THAT MORN.
AND WEEP WITH THOSE THAT WIPE.
WE TELL THEM.
YOU HAVE TO TAKE IT A DAY AT A
TIME.
>> I THINK BEING A PASTOR AND
OBVIOUSLY YOU ARE IN THE
MINISTRY AS WELL.
AND FIRST RESPONDERS AND YOU
ARE SE THESE AND HOW TO
YOU COMPARTMENTALIZE.
I PRAY FOR PEOPLE IN THALT
ARAND THEY ARE TREATED IN THE
CANCER CENTER AND SOME OF THEM
ARE NOT GOING TO MAKE IT.
MD SOP SON IS A GREAT PLACE.
>> I WILL GO BACK THERE