♪
>> SPECIAL EDITION OF THE FOX
REPORT CONTINUOUS LIVE IN A
COMMUNITY THAT IS REELING FROM
A DEVASTATING ATTACK AND NOW
THE SHOOTER'S FAMILY FOR THE
FIRST TIME RISPONDS.
-- RESPONDS.
TRACK A MASS MURDERER.
>> DETECTIVES WILL ANALYZE
EVERYTHING AND PUT A COMPLETE
PICTURE TOGETHER FROM THE
EVIDENCE THEY OBTAIN.
FROM THE HOME SHE STRUCK AND
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL BUT NOT
BEFORE EXTINGUISHING THE LIVES
OF CHILDREN.
>> THEY WERE CUTE KIDS.
THEY WERE FIRST GRADERS.
IT IS IT THE KIND OF STUFF
THAT YOU SEND YOUR KID GRAND
KIDS OUT THE DOOR TO FIRST
GRADE.
>> FOX REPORT AND THE BRAND
NEW DETAILS WE LEARNED ABOUT
THE CONNECTICUT SHOOTING
INVESTIGATION.
I AM BILL HIMER.
LIVE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT. E.
FOX REPORT.
36 HOURS REMOVED FROM A GUNMAN
UNLEASHING A SHOOTING MASSACRE
IN THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
POPULATION 600 STUDENTS FROM
KINDERGARTEN TO FOURTH.
IT IS A DAY THAT CHANGED THE
HOUSETOWN FOREVER.
MACHINES -- MEMBERS OF THE
SHOOTER FAMILY RELEASING A
STATEMENT SAYING THEY FELT
HEART FELT SORROW.
EACH OF THE 22 CHILDREN WHO
DIED WAS AGED 6 OR 7 AND ALL
THOUGHT TO BE IN THE FIRST
GRADE.
12 OF THEM WERE GIRLS AND
EIGHT WERE BOYS, THE GUNMAN
SHOT CHILD MULTIPLE TIMES.
WE ARE TOLD THAT AT LEAST ONE
CHILD WAS SHOT 11 TIMES INSIDE
OF THE CLASSROOM.
THIS IS A PICTURE OF THE
GUNMAN IDENTIFIED AS 20 YEAR
OLD ADAM LANZA THAT IS A
PICTURE FROM SIX YEARS AGO AT
THE AGE OF 14.
HE LIVED WITH HIS MOTHER IN
THE TOWN OF NEWTOWN 10 MILES
FROM THE SCHOOL.
A SCHOOL THAT HE DROVE HIS OWN
MOTHER'S CAR TO WAKING UP IN
THE MORN SHOOTING HER IN THE
HEAD.
TODAY WE HEARD FROM THE
SHOOTER'S AUNT.
SHE SAID THE MOTHER HOME
SCHOOLED HIM AFTER A DISPUTE
WITH THE PUBLIC SCHOOL SYSTEM,
BUT NO ONE IN THE FAMILY
EXPECTED HIM TO BE RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE HORROR THAT OCCURRED
HERE YESTERDAY MORNING.
>> THERE WAS CHALLENGES IN THE
FAMILY HOUSE.
NEVER IN TROUBLE WITH THE LAW
OR ANYTHING.
>> DAN MALLOY GRATE SAID THE
FAMILIES IN NEWTOWN LOST 20 OF
THEIR CHILDREN TOO SOON.
>> WHAT IS IMPORTANT IS LOVE,
COURAGE AND COMPASSION LOVE
POURED IN FROM AROUND THE
WORLD.
>> FROM AROUND THE WORLD
INDEED.
RIO DEJAENERO RELATIVES OF
CRIME VICTIMS SET UP A MAKE
SHIFT MEMORIAL FOR THE
SHOOTING VICTIMS.
IN BRAZIL THEY UNDERSTAND THE
PAIN OF SENSELESS VIOLENCE .
MOLLY LINE WORKING THE STORY
WITH ME FOR THE PAST FEW DAYS
AND THE INFORMATION THAT, IT
DOESN'T GET BETTER.
>> IT IS A CHALLENGE 24 HOURS
AFTER THE SHOOTING OCCURRED.
THE HOURS GROW LONGER.
YOU IT IS GETTING CONFUSING.
NOW FEDERAL AUTHORITIES SAYING
ADAM LANZA MAY HAVE HAD
ASBERGER SYNDROME AND
ESTRANGED FROM HIS FAMILY.
HIS FATHER AND BROTHER HADN'T
SPOKEN TO HIM IN SEVERAL YEARS
AND HIS MOTHER NANCY, DID NOT
WORK AT THE SCHOOL WHICH
LEAVES OPEN TO FURTHER
QUESTIONS AS TO WHY IT WAS
THAT THE SHOOTER WENT TO THE
SCHOOL.
NMUCH OF THE REPORT YESTERDAY
SUGGESTED SHE WAS A TEACHER AT
THE SCHOOL AND NOW THAT IS IT
SET ASIDE.
WE LEARNED FROM OFFICIALS,
THEY ARE BEGGING REPORTERS AND
THE MEDIA TO GIVE THE FAMILY
PEACE AND STAY AWAY.
ONE STATE TREEPER IS ASSIGNED
TO EACH OF THE FAMILIES.
>> EACH FAMILY HAS A STATE
TROOPER ASSIGNED FOR THEM.
SOMEONE TO DIRECTLY
COMMUNICATE WITH AND GIVING
THE FAMILIES A POINT PERSON
AND POLICE OFFICERS AND
INVESTIGATORS A POINT PERSON.
THEY ARE TAKE GOOD CARE OF THE
FAMILIES AND KEEPING LINES OF
COMMUNICATION AS OPEN AS
POSSIBLE.
NDO WE THINK THAT THE STATE
POLICE WILL TALK AGAIN
TONIGHT.
>> THEY ARE NOT EXPECTED TOMPT
THEY RELEASED WHAT THEY CAN
AND TOMORROW WILL BE ANOTHER
BRIEFING.
BUT AT THIS POINT IN TIME, IT
IS IT ABOUT THE FAMILIES THAT
ARE JUST BEGINNING TO COPE AND
HAVE ACCESS TO THE LOVED ONES.
>> MOLLY, THARCHING YOU IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> THE MEDICAL EXAMINER TALKED
ABOUT HOW THEY WENT IN TO
IDENTIFY THE YOUNG BODIES.
AND WAYNE CARVER WAS BRIEFING
REPORTERS.
HE SAID THEY DID NOT BRIPPING
THE FAMILIES INSIDE OF THE
SCHOOL.
THEY TOOK PICTURES WAS FACIAL
FEATURES OF THE SIX AND SEN
YEAR OLD CHILDREN AND BROUGHT
THEM TO THE FAMILY FOR
POSITIVE IDENTIFICATION.
IT IS IT A STORY LATE LAST
NIGHT DID NOT GET ANY BETTER
AND THAT HAS BEEN THE CASE.
WE'LL GO SLOWLY TO THE PROCESS
OF THE FUNERALS .
YOU HAVE PEOPLE HITTING THE
CLOSE KNIT COMMUNITY HARD.
WE HEARD FROM ONE MOMENTS AGO,
THEIR LIVES ARE CHANGED
FOREVER.
THESE RESIDENT ARE TRYING
THEIR BEST TO CONSOLE EACH
OTHER.
MIKE KOBIN IS IN THE CENTER OF
NOW TOWN.
NBILL, ONE OF THE THINGS YOU
NOTICE, THE FLAG IS AT HALF
STAFF.
THE CHRISTMAS DECORATIONS ARE
MISSING.
THEY FELT GUILTY ABOUT
CELEBRATING AND THEY TOOK THE
CHRISTMAS DECORATIONS DOWN.
THEY ARE DEPENDING ON EACH
OTHER A BIT.
AND PEOPLE ARE COMING TO THE
ST. ROSE OF LIMA CATHOLIC
CHURCH.
THAT IS ONE LOCATION TO COME
AND GRIEVE.
AND TO DRAW ON THE BONDS
FORGED A MAUL TOWN TO GET EACH
-SMALL TOWN.
>> AND I DON'T KNOW.
OUR FOCUS IS THE KIDS.
WE HAVE ENOUGH TIME DEALING
WITH IT AS ADULTS, PROCESSING
ALL OF THE INFORMATION AND
WHAT TRANSPIRED.
BUT THE FOCUS IS THE KID TRY
TO GET THEM THROUGH THIS.
>> ALL OF THE SCHOOLS IN THE
AREA WENT IN LOCK DOWN MODE.
COUPLE OF CHILDREN IN THE
MIDDLE SCHOOL EXPLAINED WHAT
HAPPENED WHEN THEY REALIZED IT
WAS NOT A DRILL.
>> ALL OF THE KIDS WHO HAD
SIBLINGS THERE WENT IN A STATE
OF PANIC AND FREAKING OUT.
CRYING AND THEY WERE SO
WORRIED THEY DIDN'T KNOW WHAT
TO DO.
NAND AS MUCH AS THEY ARE
DEPENDING ON EACH OTHER.
THEY HAVE BROUGHT IN GRIEF
COUNSELORS FROM THE NEIGHBORS
STATES.
THEY SET UP A CENTER IN THE
SCHOOL WITH TWO DIFFERENT
PLACES FOR THE ADULTS AND
CHILDREN, BILL.
>> WE UNDERSTAND THAT MANY OF
THEM ARE TAKING ADVANTAGE OF
THAT.
MIKE TO BIN THANK YOU.
NAND THE MEDICAL EXAMINER A
MOMENT AGO TALKED ABOUT THE
DEVASTATING INJURIES TO THE
YOUNG SO TINY BODIES.
HE DRIBED SOME AS BEING SHOT
THREE TIMES AND HE SAID ONE
BODY THAT HE TOOK CARE OF WAS
SHOT LEN TIMES AND HOW THAT IS
POSSIBLE INSIDE OF THE COOL
AND CLASSROOM DEFIES
IMAGINATION.
WE ARE LEARNING ABOUT ANOTHER
SHOOTING.
THIS ONE IN THE STATE OF
ALABAMA.
IT HAPPENED IN BIRMINGHAM.
THEY GOT A CALL ABOUT AN ARMED
MAN WALKING IN ST. VIN CENT'S
HOSPITAL.
MEAS SAY HE OPENED FIRE.
AND AN OFFICER WAS HIT AND
WOUNDED AND THE OTHER OFFICER
FIRING BACK AND KILLING THE
SUSPECT.
TWO HOSPITAL EMPLOYEES WERE
WOUND THER ALL EXPECTED TO BE
OKAY.
THERE IS ANOTHER STORY IN
OKLAHOMA WE WANT TO BRING
ATTENTION TO A SCHOOL SHOOT
BOMB PLOT THAT WAS FOILED
PLANNED FOR THE SAME DAY AS
THE TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN.
BARTERSVILLE 50 MILES NORTH OF
TULSA, 18 YEAR OLD SAMMY
CHAVEZ WAS PLANNING TO KILL
HIS HIGH SCHOOL CLASS MATES.
HE PLAN TOD LURE THEM IN THE
HIGH SCHOOL AUDITORIUM AND
CHAIN IT AND SET OFF BOMBS AND
SHOOTING.
HE IS HELD ON A MILLION
DOLLARS BOND.
WE HEARD FROM THE FATHER A
LITTLE EARLIER TODAY.
ROBBY PARKER HAD SAID MY
DAUGHTER ,
LIGHT UP THE ROOM AND HAD
SOMETHING NICE TO SAY ABOUT
EVERYONE.
WE REMEMBER EMILY TONIGHT AND
ALL OF THE OTHERS IN A
COVERAGE THAT STUNNED THE
NATION .
YOU WILL HEAR THE RADIO
TRANSMISSIONS OF THE POLICE
RUSHING TO THE SCENE.
TRYING TO SAVE THE CHILDREN,
SOME OF THEM WHO DIDN'T STAND
A CHANCE.
>> I HAVE BODIES HERE.
BUT GET THE AMBULANCES .
THIS IS AMERICA.
WE DON'T LET FREQUENT HEARTBURN
COME BETWEEN US
AND WHAT WE LOVE.
SO IF YOU'RE ONE OF THEM PEOPLE
WHO GETS HEARTBURN
AND THEN TREATS DAY AFR DAY...
BLOCK THE ACID WITH PRILOSEC OTC
AND DON'T GET HEARTBURN
IN THE FIRST PLACE!
[ Male Announcer ]
E PILL EACHMORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBUR
Neural speeds
increasing to 4G LTE.
Brain upgrading to a quad-core
processor.
Predictive intelligence
with Google Now complete.
Introducing DROID DNA by HTC.
It's not an upgrade
to your phone.
It's an upgrade to yourself.
♪ OOH BABY,
CAN I DO FOR YOU TODAY? ♪
[ Female Announcer ] NEED HELP
KEEPING YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE?
ALIGN CAN HELP.
NLY ALIGN HAS BIFANTIS,
A PATENTED PROBIOTIC
THAT NATURALLY HELPS MAINTAIN
YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE.
TRY ALIGN TO HELP RETAIN
A BALANCED DIGESTIVE SYSTEM.
TRY THE #1 GASTROENTEROLOGIST
RECOMMENDED PROBIOTIC.
ALIGN.
>> IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
DOZENS OF STATE TROOPERS
RESPOND HAPPENED TO THE 911
CALL AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL DOWN IN THE PARKING
LOT.
ONE BUILDING, IN A SQUARE
SHAPE AND COURT YARD IN THE
MIDDLE.
THERE IS CAR AFTER CAR LINED
UP UNMARKED FROM THE STATE
TROOPERS HERE FROM CONNECTICUT
AND OTHER INVESTIGATORS
CARRYING OUT THE GRISLY
OPERATION IN A CHILLY AND COLD
NIGHT IN SOUTHEASTERN
CONNECTICUT.
YESTERDAY MORNING, RIGHT
AROUND 9:30 EASTERN TIME .
SHE THINKS THAT EVERYONE IS
SHOOTING.
THEY ARE UNSURE WHY.
>>
THERE WILL BE MANY MORE AUDIO
RECORDINGS LIKE THAT, THAT
TELL THE DRAMATIC STORY OF
WHAT IS HAPPENING WHEN THE
POLICE OFFICERS WALKED IN THE
SCENE OF CARNAGE INSIDE THE
DELASS ROOM.
THERE WERE BROKEN WINDOWS IN
THE SCHOOL.
STATE POLICE BROKE GLASS TO
GET IN THE SCHOOL AND TRY TO
SAVE YOUNG KIDS.
THERE WAS A THOUGHT THAT THE
GUNMAN HAD FIRED BULLETS
THROUGH THE GLASS DOOR TO GAIN
ACESS INSIDE .
THAT IS NOT THE CASE BASED ON
WHAT THE POLICE ARE TELLING US
IN NEWTOWN.
THE REASON WHY IT IS
IMPORTANT, IT SHOWS YOU THE
PAIN STAKING DETAIL THER GOING
TO PIECE TOGETHER ALL OF THE
BULLETS AND CASINGS AND BODIES
WERE INSIDE TO TRY TO GET AN
ACCURATE DEPICTION OF WHAT
TOCK PLACE.
THAT'S WHY THE INVESTIGATION
IS MOVINGACIOUS LONG AT THE
PACE IT MOVES.
THE COUNTRY'S LEADERSHIPS
EXPRESSING HEART BREAK.
THE REPUBLICANS CANCELLED THE
WEEKLY RADIO ADDRESS AND SAID
THE PRESIDENT SHOULD SPEAK FOR
ALL AMERICANS .
MOLLY IS LIVE IN WASHINGTON ON
THAT PART OF THE STORY.
NBILL, OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN
TODAY.
THAT'S WHAT PRESIDENT OBAMA
SAID IN HIS WEEKLY RADIO AND
INTERNET ADDRESS.
HE DEVOTED THE ENTIRE ADDRESS
TO THE SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT, AND SAID THE
NATION GRIEVES FOR THE
FAMILIES WHO LOST LOVED ONES.
>> THIS WEEKEND, MICHELLE AND
I ARE DOING WHAT EVERY PARENT
IS DOING.
HOLDING OUR CHILDREN AND
REMINDING THEM HOW MUCH WE
LOVE THEM.
THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CAN'T DO THAT
TODAY AND THEY NEED ALL OF US
RIGHT NOW.
NOTHING CAN TAKE THE PLACE OF
A LOST CHILD OR LOVED ONE.
ALL OF US CAN EXTEND A HAND TO
THOSE IN NEED TO REMIND US
THAT WE ARE THERE FOR THEM.
NFLAGS ARE LOWERED TO HALF
STAFF IN THE CAPITOL.
REPUBLICANS USUALLY DO A
WEEKLY ADDRESS OF THEIR OWN.
NOT TODAY.
THE PRESIDENT WOULD SPEAK IN
THE TIME OF MOURNING.
BOEHNER SAID IN A PAPER
STATEMENT, THE HORROR OF THIS
DAY SEEMS SO UNBEARABLE.
WE WILL LOCK ARMS THAT'S HOW
THE AMERICANS RISE ABOVE
UNSPEAKABLE EVIL AND LET'S
COME TOGETHER TO PRAY FOR THE
FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS THAT
THEY MAY FIND CAN HAVE THE AND
PEACE AMID SUCH SUFFERING.
JANET NAPAL TANO SAID THAT
DEPARTMENT WILL PROVIDE ANY
ASSISTANCE NEEDED.
WE ARE LEARNING THAT PRESIDENT
OBAMA WILL COME TO NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT TOMORROW.
IT WAS NOT CLEAR WHEN IT WOULD
HAPPEN AND THE WORLD IS
CONFIRMED TO OUR FOX CREW IN
THE WHITE HOUSE.
WE EXPECT FUNERALS AND ALL
LIKELIHOOD TO START ON MONDAY
OR POSSIBLY NEXT WEEK AND THAT
WILL BE THE NEXT RIPPLE AND
YOU CAN STEE THE NEXT WAVE OF
HORROR IN THIS STORY AS WE
LEARN MORE ABOUT THE PERSONAL
LIVES OF THOSE CHANGED FOREVER
AND THE PEOPLE GUNNED DOWN
INSIDE OF THAT SCHOOL.
THE PRINCIPAL WE KNOW HAD BEEN
THE PRINCIPAL FOR LAST TWO
YEARS AND A WELL LIKED WOMAN.
AGE 47 AND HAD FIVE KIDS AT
HOME TWO DAUGHTERS OF HER OWN
AND THREE STEP DAUGHTERS.
HER HUSBAND GEORGE WAS ALSO A
TEACHER HERE IN THE DISTRICT.
YOUR HEART GOES OUT TO WHAT
HE'S GOING THROUGH NOW WITH
FIVE CHILDREN MISSING A
MOTHER.
WE HEAR FROM A FATHER.
ROBBY PARKER TALKING ABOUT HIS
LITTLE GIRL EMILY KILLED IN
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND THE
MESSAGE THAT THE HEART FATHER
IS SHARING FOR THE SHOOTER'S
FAMILY AND NATION .
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
RED LOBSTER'S
HITTING THE STREETS
TO TELL REAL PEOPLE ABOUT
OUR NEW 15 UNDER $15 MENU.
OH MY GOODNESS!
OH MY GOSH,
THIS LOOKS AMAZING!
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR NEW MAINE STAYS!
15ENTREES UNDER $15,
SEAFOOD, CHICKEN AND MORE!
OOTHE TILAPIAWITH ROASTEDEGETAB!
I'M ACTUALLY LOOKING AT
THE WO GRILLED CHICKEN
WITH PORTOBELLO WINE SAUCE.
AT PORK CHOP
WAS GREAT!
NO MORE
FAST FOOD FRIDAY'S!
WE'RE GOING TO GO
TO RED LOBSTER.
YEP.
[ Male Announcer ]
COME TRY OUR NEW MENU
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
SALAD, SANDWICHES, AND MORE.
>> I MENTIONED THROUGHOUT THE
EVENING THE NAME ROBBY PARKER
.
HE MET RESPIRATORIES TWO HOURS
AGO AND THIS IS PART OF THE
PROCESS OF GRIEVING AND HOW
YOU TRY TO FIGURE OUT YOUR SIX
YEAR OLD DAUGHTER EMILY IS NOT
COMING HOME AND WILL NOT BE
THERE FOR CHRISTMAS IN 10
DAYS.
ROBBY PARKER HAS THREE KIDS
AGES THREE, FOUR, AND 6.
HE LOST THE 6 YEAR OLD .
HE MET WITH THE REPORTERS AND
WE THOUGHT IT WAS IMPORTANT TO
SHARE WITH THE VIEWERS.
THE MESSAGE HE HAS FOR TRYING
TO COME TO GRIPS WITH THIS
TRAGEDY AND WHAT HE WANTS THE
COUNSELRY TO KNOW.
THIS IS ROBBY PARKER IN HIS
OWN WORDS.
>> CONTACTED BY SO MANY PEOPLE
AND AGENCIES UPONING TO KNOW
HOW WE ARE DOING, AND I
THOUGHT THIS WAS THE BEST WAY
TO SHARE MY FEELINGS.
FIRST OF ALL I WOULD REALLY
LIKE TO OFFER OUR DEEPEST
CONDOLENCES TO ALL OF THE
FAMILIES DIRECTLY AFFECTED BOY
THE SHOOTING IT IS IT A
HORRIVE BEING TRAGEDY AND OUR
HEARTS AND PRAYERS GO OUT TO
THEM.
THIS INCLUDES THE FAMILY OF
THE SHOOTER.
I CAN'T IMAGINE HOW HARD THIS
EXPERIENCE MUST BE FOR YOU.
I WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT OUR
FAMILY AND OUR LOVE AND
SUPPORT GOES OUT TO YOU AS
WELL.
AT THIS TIME SO MANY FRIENDS
AND FAMILY AND COMPLETE
STRANGERS WHO WE DON'T KNOW
FOR ALL OF THE LOVE AND
COLDOLLENCES AND SUPPORT YOU
HAVE BEGINITOUS.
MY DAUGHTER EMILY WOULD BE ONE
OF THE FIRST TO BE TAND GIVE
YOUR LOVE AND SUPPORT TO ALL
OF THE VICTIMS, BECAUSE THAT
IS THE TICH PERSON SHE IS.
NOT BECAUSE OF ANY PARENTING
THAT WE DID.
BUT BECAUSE THOSE WERE THE
GIFTS BEGIN TO HER BY HER
HEAVENLY FATHER.
WE FIND COMFORT REFLECTING ON
THE INCREDIBLE PERSON THAT
EMILEE WAS AND HOW MANY LIVES
SHE WAS ABLE TO TOUCH IN HER
SHORT TIME HERE ON EARTH.
EMILEE WAS BRIGHT AND CREATIVE
AND VERY LOAVING AND ALWAYS
DOING TO DO THINGS .
SHE LOVED TO USE YOUR TALENTS
TO EVERYONE.
AND SHE WAS AN EXCEPTIONAL
ARTIST AND NEVER MISSED AN
OPPORTUNITY TO DRAW A PICTURE
OR MAKE A CARD FOR THOSE
AROUND HER.
I CAN'T COUNT THE NUMBER OF
TIME EMILEE NOTICED MACHINE
FEELING SAD OR FRUSTRATED AND
WOULD RUSH TO DRAW THEM A
PICTURE OR WRITE THEM A NOTE.
HER CARD MAKING WAS EXPRESSED
IN OCTOBER WHEN SHE PLACED A
SPECIAL CARD SHE HAD MADE IN
THE CASKET OF HER GRAND
DAUGHTER WHO DIED IN A TRAGIC
ACCIDENT RECENTLY.
SHE WAS A MENTOR TO HER TWO
LITTLE SISTERS AND TEACHING
THEM HOW TO READ AND DANCE AND
KNOW THE SIMPLE JOYS OF LIFE.
HER LAUGHER WAS INFECTOUS AND
ALL WHO HAD THE PLEASURE TO
MEET HER, AGREE THAT IT IS A
BETTER PLACE BECAUSE SHE WAS
IN IT.
AS WE MOVE ON FOR WHAT
HAPPENED HERE AND HAPPENED TO
SO MANY PEOPLE.
IT IS SOMETHING TO INSPIRES US
TO BE BETTER AND MORE
COMPASSIONATE AND MORE HUMBLE
PEOPLE.
LET US PLEASE KEEP THE
CENTISTS -- SENTIMENTS OF LOVE
FOR OUR FAMILY AND COMPASSION
TO STRANGERS AND KEEP THEM
WITH US AT ALL TIMES AND NOT
JUST IN TIMES OF SORROW AND
TRAGEDY AND MAY WE DO THIS SO
WE BETTER ALL OF OUR
COMMUNITIES AND ALL OF OUR
STATES AND THAT WE MAKE
EVERYONE IN THIS COUNTRY FEEL
SAFE.
THANK YOU.
AND I WOULD BE HAPPY TO WORRY
ANY QUESTIONS.
>> AND WHERE IN THE WORLD DO
YOU BEGIN NOW IN
ROBBY PARKER WENT ON TO SAY HE
LIVED IN THE AMERICAN WEST AND
MOVED TO NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
EIGHT MONTHS AGO AND THE FOLKS
IN THE WEST SAID YOU HAVE TO
BE TOUGH IN THE EAST COAST
BECAUSE THOSE FOLKS ARE NOT
NICE.
HE TALKED ABOUT HOW LOVING THE
COMMUNITY HAS BEEN SINCE THE
FIRST DAY HE MOVED HERE AND HE
HAD NOT REGRETTED IT CBS.
HIS TWO OTHER DAUGHTERS AGED
TWO AND FOUR.
HE SAID I DON'T KNOW HOW TO
GET THROUGH THIS.
THE BEST THING I CAN DO IT
HELP OTHER PEOPLE AND THEN
ABOUT EMILEE.
I AM SO BLESSED TO BE HER
FATHER.
I AM SO BLESSED TO BE HER DAD.
THIS IS IT THE FIRST OF SO
MANY STORIES AS WE MOVE TO THE
FUNERALS NEXT WEEK AND
MEMORIAL SERVICES UNDERWAY.
THE PRESIDENT COMES HERE
TOMORROW TO NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT AND WE'LL OF THAT
VISIT.
WE'LL CHECK IN ON THE
SIGNIFICANT STORIES WE ARE
WATCHING TODAY INCLUDING THE
CHOICE FOR THE NEXT SECRETARY
OF STATE.
AND LATEST ON WHAT IS
HAPPENING IN NEWTOWN AND
RELATIVES OF THE SHOOTER GIVE
THEIR RESPONSE.
IT TOOK THE LIVES OF 21
CHILDREN AGES 6-7.
WHERE DO YOU GO FROM HERE IN
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
JILL AND HER MOUTH HAVE LIVED
A GREAT LIFE.
BUT SHE HAS SOME DENTAL ISSUES
SHE'S NOT HAPPY ABOUT.
SO I INTRODUCED JILL
TO CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SELECTED FOR PEOPLE OVER 50.
PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE IS A
TOOTHPASTE THAT DEFENDS AGAINST
TENDER, INFLAMED GUMS,
SENSITIVITY AND WEAK ENAMEL.
CONDITIONS PEOPLE OVER 50
EXPERIENCE.
CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SO JILL CAN KEEP LIVING
THE GOOD LIFE.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
>> LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT FOR THE SPECIAL
EDITION OF FOX REPORT.
GOOD EVENING TO YOU WHERE EVER
YOU ARE.
ONLY 36 HOURS AFTER THAT MAD
MAN BURST IN THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, KILLING 12
YOUNG GIRLS AND 8 BOYS AND SIX
ADULTINGS.
ALL OF THE CHILDREN WERE
EITHER 6 OR 7 AND THE LAST
HOUR, RELATIVES OF THE
SHOTTER.
ADAM LAMB RELEASED A STATEMENT
PART OF WHICH READS THE
FOLLOWING.
>> WE REACH OUT TO THE
COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN AND
EXPRESS HEART FELT SORROW FOR
THE PROFOUND LOSS OF INNOCENCE
THAT IS AFFECTED SO MANY.
WITH ME NOW MY COLLEAGUES ARE
GOING TO BE BROADCASTING HERE
LIVE LATER ON TONIGHT.
WE HAVE BEEN THROUGH TOUGH
ONES AND THIS IS RIGHT NEAR
THE TOP.
>> YES.
IT IS SO WRONG.
NYES, MY SENYEAR OLD FIRST
GRADERS AND THIS IS IT SO
AGREDGOUS AND DEVASTATING AND
AWFUL TO MOY.
-- ME.
YOU HAVE THE SHOCK AND
OUTRAGE, AND ALSO THERE IS A
FEELING OF DISGUST AT THIS
MONSTER WHO WOULD TORTEUR
THESE CHILDREN.
REMEMBER BILLY BURSTS IN THE
ROOM AND STARTS KILLING THE
CHILDREN.
THEY WERE ALIVE AND DEAD AND
DYING, AND HE HAS A LONG RIFLE
AND RIGHT UP TO THE KIDS .
HE'S ALMOST THE AGENT OF THE
DEVIL'S APOCALYPSE.
IT IS RAW AND SAVE ANNUAL.
IT IS A MINI HOLOCAUST.
>> I THOUGHT THE STATEMENTS BY
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER WERE
CHILLING THAT I HAVE HEARD OF
ALL OF THE CHILLING STORIES
THAT WE HEARD IN THE PAST DAY
AND HALF.
YOU MUST BE OF THAT MIND SET
IN ORDER TO ENDURE WHAT THAT
MAN HAS ENDURED.
SOME OF KIDS WERE SHOT 11
TIMES.
WHERE WERE THEY SHOT.
HE SAID EVERYWHERE.
YOU START TO THINK WHAT COULD
POSSIBLY HAVE BEEN THE MOTIVE?
WHAT COULD HAVE POSSIBLE
CREATED THE RAGE FOR YOU TO
COMMIT THAT OBSCENE VIOLENCE
AGAINST THE CHILDREN AND TO
DRESS IN COMBAT GEAR AND ARM
YOURSELF WITH COMBAT STYLE
WEAPONS AND THEP GO AND NOT
TAKE ON AN ENEMY DEFENDING
YOUR COUNTRY, BUT PICK ON THE
VULNERABLE AND INNOCENT
CHILDREN AND CHILDREN NEVER
EXPOSED TO ANYTHING EVIL
BEFORE AND NEVER HAD AN ADULT
TREAT THEM WITH ANYTHING BUT
LOVE AND AFFECTION.
HE WAS DRESSED IN A COSTUME
AND STYLING HIMSELF AS A
WARRIOR AGAINST WHAT?
AGAINST CHILDREN?
THE MOST VULNERABLE PEOPLE IN
OUR SOCIETY.
THAT DEEPLY SICKENS ME AND
EVERYONE OF THOSE CHILDREN.
WHAT COULD HAVE BEEN GONE ON
BEHIND THOSE BANGS AND WHAT IS
IT IN THIS PERSON THAT HE
COULD DO IT TO THE CHILDREN.
WE HAVE BEEN AROUND AND I HAVE
KNOWN YOU FOR YEARS AND THIS
IS GUT WRERCHING.
IT BRINGS YOU TO TEARS.
IT JUST -- YOU WANT TO VOMIT,
IT IS JUST A TERRIBLE,
TERRIBLE SITUATION.
NI MENTIONED EARLIER THAT SO
MANY PEOPLE TOLD ME THEY TURN
ON THE TV AND STARE AT IT AND
LEAVE IT ON FOR HOURS.
AND THEY SIT THERE IN TEAR
CRYING OVER THE ENORMOUS LOSS.
AND AS A FATHER, YOU THINK OF
YOUR 7 YEAR OLD DAUGHTER.
>> YOU NOT.
I LOOK AT YOU NOW.
WE TRY TO MAINTAIN OUR
COMPOSURE.
WE ARE PROFESSIONALS AND I AM
A WAR CORRESPONDANT AND SEEN
ATROCITY IN IRAQ AND SOMALIA
AND EVERYWHERE ELSE.
LOOK AT THE VICTIMS HOW
SELECTIVE HE WAS.
FIRST GRADERS.
SIX YEARS OLD AND 7 YEARS OLD.
AND ANY WONDER THE PRESIDENT
WAS MOVED TO TEARS AND THE
NATION WAS MOVED TO TEARS AND
THE POPE, IT IS SO
UNFATHOMABLE.
WHAT COULD HAVE HAPPENED TO
THIS PERSON THAT HE WOULD IN
ANY WAY FEEL THAT HE WAS
CERTIFIED TO COMMIT THIS
OBACCEPTITY.
THIS WILL GO DOWN IN HISTORY
TO BE A DAY THAT WILL LIVE IN
INFAMY AND THE MAKE OF A
BEAUTIFUL NEW ENGLAND COMMUN A
PLACE OF HORROR AND FEAR FOR
THESE CHILDREN?
I CAN'T, I CAN'T, I SWEAR, IT
IS THE NATION'S NIGHTMARE,
BILL, TO THINK OF THE LIVES
THEY LED FROM THE MOMENT HE
BURST IN THEIR CLASSROOM AND
ENDED THEIR LIVES.
WHAT COULD THOSE CHILDREN HAVE
BEEN THINKING.
YOU THINK ABOUT THAT AND YOU
WANT TO TAKE HIS REMAINS AND
THROW THEM TO THE WINDS AND SO
THER NOT THERE. SO EVIL.
NTHIS HAPPENED IN SOUTHERP
RUSSIA.
AND THIS HAPPENED IN NORWAY IN
THE ISLAND A YEAR AGO, AND NOW
HAPPENED HERE AND WE HAVE HAD
SCHOOL SHOOTINGS BEFORE, BUT
NEVER HITTING A 6 YEAR OLD
CHILD 11 TIMES WITH A RIFLE.
NLOOK AT HOW COLUMBINE SCARRED
US AND CHANGED THE WAY SCHOOLS
ARE GUARD RUN AND THOSE WITH
TEENAGERS AND GOD HELP US IT
WAS HORRIBLE.
NOW TAKE IT DOWN TO FIRST
GRADERS.
I RAN UP TOWN TO SEE MY
DAUGHTER.
PICTURE THE LITTLE CHILDREN IN
THE LITTLE OUTFITS AND THEIR
LUNCHES AND WHAT ARE THEY
THINKING ABOUT.
THERE A ARE THINKING ABOUT
PLAY DATES AND LEGOS AND DOLLS
AND CHRISTMAS.
>> THEY ARE THINKING ABOUT
CHRISTMAS AND STANTA CLAUSE
AND HE WAS GOING TO BE HERE IN
10 DAYS.
>> IMAGINE, WHAT WILL
CHRISTMAS BE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT WILL IT ALWAYS BE
THIS MEMORY?
IT IS DIFFICULT TO REPORT IN A
SOBER, SOMBER WAY BECAUSE IT
IS IT SO EMOTION.
IT IS DIFFICULT NOT TO BE
IMPRESSIONED AND OBVIOUSLY
OVER COME WITH GROVEAND
SORROW.
>> WE'LL SEE YOU TONIGHT.
>> HANG TOUGH.
>> YOU, TOO.
N10 O'CLOCK.
>> YES.
SEE YOU THEN.
>> MUCH MORE TONIGHT FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
10 O'CLOCK EASTERN TIME WITH A
SPECIAL EDITION OF GERALDO AT
LARGE.
>> THANK YOU, MY FRIEND.
>> AS THE NATION TRIES TO
FIGURE THIS OUT AND PARENTS
TRY TO MAKE A CONNECTION TO
WHAT HAPPENED HERE AND YOU
CONSIDER THE INNOCENT LIVES
LOST IN NEWTOWN.
MANY ARING AND THINKING OF
THOSE WHO SURVIVED.
THEY ARE KINDERGARTENS WHO
JUST LIVED THROUGH THAT NO ONE
SHOULD SEE.
HOW DO THEY COPE.
DR. MARK SEIGLE IS WITH ME.
MEMBER OF THE FOX'S MEDICAL A
TEEM.
THERE IS IT A SYMPTOM CALLED
PTFD DOES SOMETHING LIKE THAT
APPLY TO A FIVE YEAR OLD
CHILD?
IT IS RUN BECAUSE OF THE WARS
AND APPLIES TO CHILDREN, AND
STATISTICS ARE SHOCKING.
77 PERCENT OF THE KIDS IN THIS
SCHOOL ARE GOING TO SUFFER
FROM THESE SYMPTOMS AND 35
PERCENT OF THE KIDS IN THE
NEIGHBORHOOD NOT EVEN AT THE
SCHOOL.
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT
DISRUPTIONS AND FEELING ALONE
AND INABILITY TO TRUST ANYONE
AND RELIVING THES IN REVERSE
ORDER AND ANTICIPATING THE
NEXT TIME IT IS GOING TO
HAPPEN.
IT TAKES WEEKS AND MONTHS FOR
KIDS TO RECOVER FROM THIS.
LUCKY PSYCHOTHERAPY HELPS .
THEY HAVE TO GET THESE KIDS IN
THERAPY.
NI WANT TO TALK A LITTLE BIT
ABOUT THAT, DOCTOR.
BUT YOU DON'T KNOW HOW KIDS
REACT OVER TIME.
ESPECIALLY WHEN YOU ARE THIS
YOUNG.
I TALKED TO A WOMAN, HER SIX
YORE OLD DAUGHTER IS OKAY.
AND HER MOTHER WAS TALKING FOR
HOURS AND FINALLY THE DAUGHTER
SAID TO THE MOM, ARE YOU GOING
TO BE OKAY?
I KNOW OUR FOCUS IS ON THE
YOUNG CHILDREN.
BUT YOU WONDER HOW THE ADULTS
MANAGE TO COMMUNICATE WITH ONE
ANOTHER.
I WOULD IMAGINE THERE IS IT A
LEVEL OF TRAUMA THAT PEEKS IN
THEIR LIVES AS WELL.
HOW DO YOU DEAL WITH THAT
THEN, DOCTOR?
>> THAT IS CRUCIAL.
AND THERE IS IT A TRAUM ATTIC
STRESS DISORDER AND AFFECT THE
FIRST REPONDERS AND PEOPLE WHO
STAW THIS.
AND WE ARE REPORTING WITH A
SHOCKING NUMBER OF WOUNDS AND
BOONS AND SOUNDS, THIS IS IT A
TOUGH ONE.
AND BEING, KIDS ARE GOING TO
LOOK TO THEIR PARENTS.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL ME AND ARE
YOU AFRAID AND DO YOU SHOW
COURAGE.
THE SAME OF THE BRAIN DEAL
WITH OUR CARING AND THEY ARE
TREMEPPEDOUS.
WE SAW THEM BREWED BY PETER
JOHNSON IN THE MORNING AND
THEY ARE BONDING TOGETHER AND
HUGGING EACH OTHER AND THAT
WILL HELP THEM GET THROUGH
THIS, BILL.
>> YEAH, THERE WAS A HEALTH
CLINIC THAT CAME OVER FROM
YALE.
DID YOU HEAR ABOUT THAT,
DOCTOR?
IT IS IT ALREADY UP AND
OPERATING.
AND THERE ARE MANY, DOZENS AND
DOZENS OF PEOPLE WHO ARE
ALREADY SEEKING HELP FROM
THEM.
WHAT DOES THAT TELL YOU.
>> THAT IS IT CRUCIAL.
ANDLET SECRET IS NOT TO SHY
AWAY FROM IT.
BUT TO ALLOW THE CHILDREN AND
ADULTS TO EXPRESS THEMSELVES
AND TALK ABOUT WHAT THEY LIVED
THROUGH.
AND NO QUESTION IS OFF LIMS
HERE AND ANSWERS HAVE TO BE
HONEST AND DIRECT AND THEY
HAVE TO BE AS THEY COME AND WE
OUTSIDE LOOKING IN ON THIS
HAVE TO REMEMBER AND WE TALK
ABOUT OUR OWN CHILDREN, BUT
BILL, OUR OWN CHILDREN ARE
SAFE IS OUR OWN SCHOOLS ARE
SAFE.
WE ARE STILL TALKING ABOUT
ONLY ONE PERCENT OF THE
HOMICIDES IN THE COUNTRY ARE
AROUND SCHOOLS.
WE HAVE TO FOCUS ON THE
CHILDREN AND SCHOOLS THAT
LIVED THROUGH IT.
LET'S TEAR CARE FOR THE PEOPLE
OUT THERE.
>> YOUR INITIAL POINT IS WELL
TAKEN IF YOU NEED HELP SEEK IT
AND DON'T RUN FROM IT.
THANK YOU.
AM THERAPY NOW WILL HELP THIM
LATER ON.
>> THANK YOU.
WE'LL CONTINUE TO FOLLOWLET
LATEST ON WHAT IS HAPPENING
HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
MORE INFORMATION WE'LL PASS TO
YOU.
BUT THERE IS IT A HEAD LINE,
TOO.
THAT WE WILL GET TO TONIGHT.
WE ARE LEARNING THAT PRESIDENT
WILL DOMINATE DEMOCRATIC JOHN
KERRY TO REPLACE OUT GOING
HILLARY CLINTON IT IS IT
BASICALLY A DONE DEAL NOW THAT
SUSAN RICE WITH DREW HER NAME
FROM CONSIDERATION.
IT WAS NOT OFFICIALLY PLACED
IN NOM NAUTION .
AND THE OFFICIAL NOMINATION
COULD COME IN THE NEXT FEW
DAYS.
WE'LL FOLLOW THAT.
AND EGYPT'S FLEDGING ATTEMPT
AT DEMOCRACY, IT COULD HINGE
ON WHAT IS HAPPENING IN THE
COUNTRY TONIGHT.
WE'LL GET THE LATEST ON THE
GROUND IN CAIRO.
AND WHEN OUR COVERAGE
CONTINUES IN NEWTOWN, WE HAVE
THE LIST OF 20 YOUNG CHILDREN
BORN IN 2005 OR 6.
ALL OF THEM EITHER AGE SIX OR
SEN.
WE REMEMBER CHASE AND DILLAN
AND MADELINE AND 17 OTHERS .
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU ARE A BUSINESS PRO.
GOVERNOR OF GETTING IT DONE.
YOU KNOW HOW TO DANCE...
WITH A DEADLINE.
AND YOU...RENT FROM NATIONAL.
BECAUSE ONLY NATIONAL LETS YOU
CHOOSE ANY CAR IN THE AISLE...
AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE A FULL-SIZE
OR ABOVE,
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
THIS IS AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS, BUSINESS PRO.
YES, IT IS.
GO NATIONAL. GO LIKE A PRO.
So we created the
extraordinarily
comfortable Sleep Number
Experience.
around a bed with DualAir
Technology that allows you
to adjust to the support
your body needs - each of
your bodies.
Our sleep professionals will
help you find
your sleep number setting.
Exclusively at a Sleep
Number store.
Sleep Number.
Comfort individualized.
This holiday season, give
the gift that's magical:
the innovative AirFit
adjustable pillow at
special 30% savings.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT STARTED LONG AGO.
THE JOY OF GIVING SOMETHING
EVERYTHING YOU'VE GOT.
IT TAKES PASSION.
AND IT'S NOT LETTING UP
ANYTIME SOON.
AT UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company,
WE UNDERSTAND THAT COMMITMENT.
AND ALWAYS HAVE.
SO DOES AARP,
AN ORGANIZATION
SERVING THE NEEDS
OF AMERICANS 50 AND OVER
FOR GENERATIONS.
SO IT'S NO SURPRISE
MILLIONS HAVE CHOSEN
AN AARP Medicare Supplement
Insurance Plan,
INSURED BY UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company.
LIKE ALL STANDARDIZED
MEDICARE SUPPLEMENT PLANS,
THEY HELP COVER
SOME OF THE EXPENSES
MEDICARE DOESN'T PAY.
AND SAVE YOU UP TO THOUSANDS
IN OUT-OF-POCKET COSTS.
TO FIND OUT MORE,
REQUEST YOUR
FREE DECISION GUIDE.
CALL OR GO ONLINE TODAY.
AFTER ALL,
WHEN YOU'RE GOING THE DISTANCE,
IT'S NICE TO HAVE
THE EXPERIENCE AND COMMITMENT
TO GO ALONG WITH YOU.
KEEP DREAMING. KEEP DOING.
GO LONG.
>> WE'LL GET BACK TO THE
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT.
FIRST FROM EGYPT TONIGHT.
THERE ARE MILLIONS OF PEOPLE
HEADING TO THE POLL TO VOTE ON
A DRAFT AND SPHUSION THAT -
CONSTITUTION THAT DEEPLY
DIVIDED THE COUNTRY.
OPPONS SAY THEY FEAR IT COULD
CRUSH RELIGIOUS FREEDOM IN
EGYPT.
AND IT IS IT A VIOLENT AND
DEADLY PROTEST.
NOT ONLY COULD IT SHAPE THE
FUTURE OF EGYPT SERIOUSLY
IMPACT THE REGION AND THEY
STREAMING LIVE IN CAIRO WITH
HOW THOO VOTE IS GOING.
GOOD EVENING.
>> POLLS HAVE NOW CLOSED HERE
IN CAIRO AND OTHER CITY IN
EGYPT AND OVER ALL IT IS OKAY
.
THERE WERE LONG LINES AND THEY
ARE HAVING VARIOUS CHARGES OF
IRREGULARITIES.
BUT NOT ENOUGH FOR THE HALTING
OF THE VOTE.
120,000 FROM THE EGYPTIAN ARMY
AND THERE ARE REPORTS WAS
CLASHES.
THE OFFICE OF THE LIBERAL
OPPOSITION PARTY WERE FIRE
BOMBED BY ISLAMIST AND THERE
WERE INJURIES.
THIS IS IT ALL ABOUT A DRAFT
CONSTITUTION PUSHED BY THE
EGYPTIAN PRESIDENT AND HIS
MUSLIM BROTHERHOOD PART.
THE ARGUMENT FOR THE NO VOTE
IS TOO ISLAMIST.
AND YES NOTE, IT IS NEEDED FOR
STABILITY.
THE YES VOTE COULD BE LIVES
AND A VICTORY COULD RESULT IN
CONTINUE AUTION OF THE
VIOLENCE.
THERE WILL BE A SECOND ROUND
OF VOTING AND THE OTHER HALF .
COUNSELRY WILL DECIDE ON THIS
AND THERE WILL BE A FINAL
RESULT.
MORE TIME FOR POLITICING AND
MORE TIME FOR TROUBLING THE
NAND WHAT A TIME FOR THAT
COUNTRY.
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN SOMETHING
SO SENSELESS TO YOUR OWN
CHILDREN IN
♪
MANY HOT DOGS
ARE WITHIN YOU.
TRY PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO,
IT'S THE POWER OF PEPTO,
BUT IT FITS IN YOUR POCKET.
NOW TELL THE WORLD
DANIEL...
OF PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO.
Uh...
Um...
Hm...
Umm...
Uh...
Oh !
The Windows Phone 8X
by HTC on Verizon.
It features easy
to navigate live tiles
that are simple
to customize.
Just pin what matters most
right to your homescreen.
Exclusively with Data Sense--
a feature that makes the most
of you plan.
Only on Verizon.
>> WE'LL UPDATE QUICKLY.
THE WHITE HOUSE SAYING THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL BE IN
CONNECTICUT TO SPEAK TO THE
FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS, THE
DEADLY SCHOOL SHOOTING AND WE
HEARD FROM THE SHOOTER'S
FAMILY AND HIS FATHER SAY NO
WORDS CAN TRULY EXPRESS HOW
HEART BROKEN WE ARE.
AND PARENTS OF THE VICTIMS
STRUGGLE WITH THEIR LOSS, THE
REST OF THE COUNTRY AND MANY
OF YOU TRYING TO COMPREHEND
HOW IT HAPPENS.
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN THE NEWS TO
THEM?
DOM NICK, A LOT OF CHILDREN
AND SCHOOL CHILDREN OUTSIDE OF
CONNECTICUT, THEY FOUND OUT
ABOUT THIS THROUGH SOCIAL
MEDIA AND WHAT ARE EXPERTS
ADVISING THEM TO PREVENT THE
HYSTERIA THAT THAT COULD
LIKELY LEAD TO, DOM NICK.
>> IT CERTAINLY CAN.
PARENTS DON'T WANT TO, AND
THEY GET DEPRAUGHT ABOUT THE
TWEETS.
AND THER ADVISING PARENTS TO
CALMLY EXPLAIN THE FACTS AND
START TO DISCUSS THEIR
FEELINGS AND FEARS AND THIS IS
IT HOW THE APPROACH TO THE
SUBJECT SHOULD BE TAKEN WITH
THEM.
TAKE A LOOK.
>> WHAT DID YOU THINK, WERE
YOU AFRAID IT COULD HAPPEN AT
YOUR SCHOOL.
WHAT IF IT HAPPENED AT YOUR
SCHOOL .
WANT TEACHERS WOULD STEP IN
AND POLICE WOULD BE THERE AND
MOMMY AND DADDY WOULD RUSH TO
THE SCHOOL THAINT BE AVADE TO
LET THEM TALK ABOUT WHAT IS IN
THEMPT
ALWAYS REATHEM IT IS SAFE TO
GO BACK TO SCHOOL ON MONDAY.
DOM NICK THANK YOU .
THAT DOES IT FOR THIS FOX
REPORT.
IT IS DECEMBER 15TH, 2012, 10
DAYS BEFORE CHRISTMAS AND I AM
BILL HIMER, THANKS FOR
WATCHING.
MIKE HUCKABEE STARTS IN A
MOMENT AS WE LEAVE YOU
TONIGHT, WE WANT TO REMEMBER
AND DANIEL AND CHARLOTTE AND
KATHERINE AND GRACE AND JACK.
♪