>> Dana: I WAS ON A HORSE.
THEY DRUGGED THE HORSE SO THEY
WOULDN'T MOVE AND THEY WERE
STUFFED.
RODEO CLOWN, I LOVE THEM.
THEY WEAR SUSPENDER, TOO.
>> Eric: LIKE "THE FIVE."
>> YOU'RE OUR RODEO CLOWN.
>> Eric: I'LL DO IT.
CAN I SAY IT?
WE ARE PROBABLY ON
"ENTERTAINMENT TONIGHT" AND
CHECK THE LOCAL LISTINGS.
"THE INSIDER."
BEFORE "ENTERTAINMENT
TONIGHT."
YOU'RE 100% RIGHT.
CHECK IT OUT.
I MADE A PREDICTION.
SEE IF THEY AIR THAT.
THAT IS IT FOR "THE FIVE."
THANK YOU FOR
>> YES, ANDY, THAT WAS OUR
ACTUAL IN BUS ENTERTAINER.
>> I FEEL LIKE YOU WERE TRYING
TO TELL ME THAT.
>> I WAS.
>> SIX YEARS GOING STRONG.
JOE STILL HAS THE PROFESSIONAL
SEEM LESSNESS IN ALL THE OTHER
SHOWS.
>> WE ARE SO GOOD.
WE ARE LIKE A WELL-OILED
MACHINE AND A HARLEM GLOBE
TROTTER.
>> IT WOULD BE ONE THING IF WE
TAPED IN ADVANCE, BUT WE ARE
LIVE SO YOU HAVE TO ROLL WITH
IT.
>> THESE MISTAKES HAPPEN.
EXACTLY.
>> IT IS LIVE TELEVISION.
THAT'S THE PRICE YOU PAY FROM
THE SPONTANEITY OF LIVE
TELEVISION.
>> IT IS LIVE TELEVISION THAT
MAKES IT WHAT IT IS.
ALL RIGHT.
GO AWAY CAPTAIN COLLAR.
LET'S WELCOME OUR FIRST GUEST,
SHE IS SO HOT HER OVEN MITTS
WEAR OVEN MITTS.
SHE CO ANCHORS ON FOX
NEWSCHANNEL AND SHE CAN
WAIVE.
WELL HE IS SO SHARP THAT
SWITCH BLADES CARRY HIM.
I WOULD LIKE TO WELCOME A
FIRST TIME GUEST.
HE IS PATRICK MILL SAP, RM --
FORMER CHIEF OF STAFF OF NEWT
GINGRICH'S CAMPAIGN.
AND HE IS CONSIDERED A FRUIT
BASKET.
MY REPULSIVE SIDEKICK, BILL
SCHULZ.
AND IF COMEDIC GENIUS WAS A
DRESSER HE WOULD FALL APART
WHEN YOU BANG HIM.
SHERROD SMALL.
>> THANK YOU, GREGORY.
>> THANK YOU.
>> I HAVE SO MUCH TO SAY, BUT
I AM SO AN DREE -- APING
GREE.
>> AND GOOD TO SEE YOU,
PINCH.
>> TODAY THE -- LINCOLN LEADS
LES MISERABLES.
IT IS POPPY-COCK WITH A SIDE
ORDER OF BALDERDASH.
♪ I DREAMED A STREAM
♪ IN TIMES GONE BY
♪ WHEN HOPE WAS HIGH
♪ AND LIFE WAS LIVING
>> WOW.
YOU GUYS WANT TO GO TO
SOMETHING?
THERE YOU GO.
>> THE WHOLE POINT OF BRINGING
UP THE BUS TOUR IS TO REMIND
PEOPLE THAT I WILL BE ON A BUS
TOUR.
IT BEGINS IN OKLAHOMA CITY ON
DECEMBER 15th.
AND THEN I HIT WICHITA, FALLS
AND WOOD LANDS AND GRAPEVINE
AND PLANO, WACO, TYLER.
GO TO GREG GUTFELD.COM AND YOU
CAN FIND OUT MORE ABOUT IT
THIS WEEK.
YOU HAVE TO GO, REALLY YOU
DO.
>> CAN I ASK A QUESTION?
>> SURE.
>> IS THAT THE ACTUAL SIZE OF
THE BUS?
>> I WOULD LAUGH HYSTERICALLY
IF THAT QUESTION HADN'T BEEN
ASKED 20 TIMES ALREADY.
>> REALLY?
OH, THEN I I AM NOT THE ONLY
ONE THAT SEES IT IS A
POSSIBILITY.
>> THE ANSWER IS A RESOUNDING
YES.
>> YOU ARE TERRIBLY RIGHT.
>> ACTUALLY THE BUS IS SMALLER
THAN THIS.
>> SHOULD WE RESPECT THEIR
LACK OF RESPECT?
AN ARMY HANDBOOK IS ADVISING
AMERICAN SOLDIERS NOT TO SPEAK
ILL OF THE TALIBAN OR SPEAK UP
FOR WOMEN'S RIGHTS IN
AFGHANISTAN.
THE PROPOSED DOCUMENT OBTAINED
BY THE "WALL STREET JOURNAL"
LINKED THE LACK OF SAVY TO
DEADLY UHING TAYS NOTING THAT
MANY OF THE CONFRONTATIONS
OCCURRED BECAUSE OF IGNORANCE
OR LACK OF EMPATHY FOR MUSLIM
AND/OR AFGHAN CULTURE RARE
NORMS.
CULTURAL NORMS.
IT IS RESULTING FROM THE
AFGHAN SECURITY FORCE MEMBER.
>> HOLD YOUR TONGUE WHEN THEY
TREAT WOMEN WORSE THAN CHRIS
BROWN DOES.
AND THE HANDBOOK CAUTIONS
DON'T MENTION HOMOSEXUALITY.
NOT EVERYONE AGREES.
SPEAKING OF DISAPPROVAL, LOOK
WHAT HAPPENS WHEN ANDY LEVY
TRIES TO LEAVE HIS APARTMENT.
JAY NICE JEANS, ANDY.
SOUNDS WEIRD IN HIS
APARTMENT.
>> SHERROD, SHOULD OUR
SOLDIERS BE MORE LIKE YOU AND
CULTURALLY SENSITIVE TO THE
TALIBAN?
>> YES, THEY SHOULD BE.
MIND YOUR BUSINESS.
YOU ARE NOT THERE TO DO A
ONE-MAN JOB AND CHANGING THEIR
MINDS AND FEELINGS ABOUT
THINGS.
DO YOUR JOB AND KEEP YOUR HEAD
DOWN.
>> I DON'T KNOW, HARRIS.
THE FACT IS SHOULD WE LOOK
AWAY AT HOW THEY TREAT WOMEN?
THEY THROW ACID IN WOMEN'S
FACES AND THEY SHOOT WOMEN FOR
ADULTERY.
>> THEY ARE TERRIBLE PEOPLE.
>> I CAN'T ARGUE WITH THAT.
I UNDERSTAND THAT.
ORIGINALLY AND ALL ALONG I
THOUGHT WE WERE IN FACT
SHERROD CHANGING HEARTS AND
MINDS.
HOW DO YOU DO THAT IF YOU
CAN'T CHANGE WHO YOU ARE?
WE HAVE SEEN WITH LONG-TERM
CONFLICTS THAT THIS KIND OF
BONDING AND SHARED CULTURAL
EXPERIENCE IS IMPORTANT WHEN
YOU ARE GOING TO BE THERE FOR
A LONGTIME.
FOR CIVILIANS WHO ARE OPEN TO
IT.
>> IT MAKES ME THINK I AM NOT
INTERESTED IN WINNING HEARTS
AND MINDS.
MAYBE WE SHOULD HIGH TALE IT
OUT OF THERE.
>> NO, YOU CAN WIN WITH HEARTS
AND MINDS.
YOU CAN PLAY GAMES WITH THE
KIDS.
>> WHAT MOVIES HAVE YOU SEEN?
>> YOU DON'T HAVE TO TALK
ABOUT HOMO SEXUALITY.
>> TEACHERS AND THEM
BASKETBALL AND FOOTBALL.
I DIDN'T SAY FRIED CHICKEN
WITH THEM.
>> PATRICK, GO AHEAD.
>> HE DIDN'T.
>> THE ONLY CONCERN THAT THIS
IS FROM IS THAT THESE AFGHAN
TROOPS THAT WERE SUPPOSED TO
BE HELPING ARE SHOOTING OUR
GUYS.
THAT'S WHAT STARTED THIS.
AND SO NUMBER ONE IF THIS IS
GOING TO HELP PREVENT THAT,
THEN LET THE BRASS DO IT.
NUMBER TWO, YOU ARE RIGHT.
WHO ARE OUR FRIENDS HERE?
WE HAVE FRIENDS AND ALLIES
THAT ARE SHOOTING US.
WE HAVE ISRAEL OUR FRIEND AND
ALLIES THAT SAY THEY ARE ON
OUR END.
IT IS A BIGGER ISSUE.
>> IT IS LIKE FRIENDS HOW YOU
CONSIDER PEOPLE FRIENDS ON
FACEBOOK.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> IT IS NOT LIKE FRIEND,
FRIENDS.
>> WE WERE STATIONED THERE
WITH MY DAD.
AND I ALWAYS THOUGHT WE TAKE
THE ACTUAL LESSONS LEARNED
FROM CONFLICTS AND THEN APPLY
THEM.
WHAT I UNDERSTAND WITH THIS
THOUGH IS THAT THE MANUAL HAS
TO BE GONE OVER BY GENERAL
ALLEN.
WE DON'T KNOW EXACTLY WHAT THE
END WILL BE.
>> VERY GOOD POINT AND WAY TO
ADD INFORMATION INTO THE STORY
THAT I WASN'T AWARE OF.
>> OKAY, SORRY.
>> I AM THE HOST HERE.
I AM SUPPOSED TO LOOK LIKE I
AM IN CONTROL.
BILL, YOU SERVED, BUT IT WAS
AT APPLEBY'S.
DO YOU HAVE ANY OPINION ON
THIS WHAT SO EVER?
>> YES, CLEAN UP YOUR TABLES.
I AM A TABLE BUSKER.
THE GUM AND ALL OF THAT STUFF,
I AM NOT GETTING PAID ENOUGH.
WE POOL OUR TIPS.
SECONDLY IF YOU WANT TO WIN
THE HEARTS AND MIND OF THE
TALIBAN YOU DECAPITATE THEM.
REACH INTO THE HEAD HOLE AND
PULL OUT THE MIND.
YOU GO INTO THE AORTA CAVITY
AND PULL OUT THE HEART.
MIND, HEART, WE WON.
SECOND OF ALL, THE PROBLEM
WITH THIS IS THEY ARE NOT JUST
TALKING ABOUT THE TALIBAN.
THEY ARE TALKING ABOUT REGULAR
AFGHANISTAN, PEOPLE.
WHAT EXACTLY ARE WE FIGHTING
FOR?
I HAVE TO WONDER IF THE ALLIES
WERE GOING TO GERMANY WERE
THEY GETTING PAMPHLETS THAT
SAID, DON'T SAY ANYTHING ABOUT
THE JEWS.
>> THAT'S EXACTLY RIGHT.
I THINK PATRICK IS CORRECT
THAT WE HAVE TO KEEP OUR
TROOPS SAFE.
BUT IF YOU MADE A PARALLEL
COMPARISON LIKE BILL DID, THE
ASSUME USION IS YOU WOULD TURN
A BLIND EYE TO ANTI-SEMITISM
OR WORSE, KILLING JEWS.
THE ONLY ANSWER IS GET THE
HELL OUT OF THERE OR DO
SOMETHING.
BUT I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
>> I GO BACK TO THE CENTER
FOREARM ME LESSONS LEARNED WHO
WROTE THIS MANUAL OUT OF FORT
LEAVENWORTH.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU COULD WIN
A LONG-TERM CONFLICT WITHOUT
MAKING FRIENDS.
DIFFERENT THAN THOSE ON
FACEBOOK.
>> YOU KNOW WHAT WOULD WIN
OVER FRIENDS?
DROPPING DVD'S OF "FRIENDS."
>> ROSS AND CHANDLER.
>> THEY LOVE WESTERN CULTURE.
NO THEY DON'T.
YOU KNOW WHAT BOTHERS ME THE
MOST?
FEMINISTS AND BETA MALES WHO
SPEND THEIR TIME ON BLOGS
GOING AFTER SEXIST BEHAVIORS
LIKE FRATERNITIES OR WALL
STREET.
STUFF LIKE THAT.
OH LOOK AT THESE GUYS.
THEY NEVER SAY ANYTHING ABOUT
THE STUFF THAT IS GOING ON
OVER THERE.
THEY ARE BAD STUFF.
>> I LIKE BETA MALES.
>> YOU ARE NOT A BETA MALE.
>> NO.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT A BETA MALE
IS.
>> IT IS THE OPPOSITE OF ALPHA
MALE.
>> AND SHERROD WANTS TO
TEACHERS AND OUR WONDERFUL
SPORT.
LOOK AT THEIR SPORT.
IT IS POLO WITH A GOAT'S
HEAD.
THERE IS A BIG DIVIDE.
>> YOU WORK WITH WHAT YOU
HAVE.
>> THEY DO THAT ONCE A YEAR
THOUGH.
JAY WE HAVE THE SUPER BOWL --
>> WE HAVE THE SUPER BOWL ONCE
A YEAR.
>> I WANT THEM TO -- YOU KNOW,
YOU CAN REALLY BOND WITH
PEOPLE JUST BEING NORMAL WITH
THEM.
>> THESE ARE PEOPLE WHO BLOW
YOU UP.
>> I KNOW YOU WANT TO MOVE ON,
BUT THESE ARE SOLDIERS AND
MARINES.
WE WANT THEM TO BE -- WE WANT
THEM TO BE SAFE, BUT WE WANT
THEM TO FIGHT OUR WARS AND GET
OUT.
AT THE POINT WE TEACHERS TEACH
THEM DIPLOMACY WON'T THEY TAKE
OVER?
>> IT IS HARD TO SLAM DUNK A
BALL WHEN THE VERTEBRAE IS
STILL ATTACHED.
>> I DON'T THINK HE SAID
THAT.
>> WE USED TO PLAY GOAT
BASKETBALL IN OUR FAMILY.
>> WE FINISHED THIS TOPIC.
>>> FROM MANUALS TO MANGERS
THEY ARE FOCUSING ON BULLIES
IN ASSISTED OF BLITZEN.
A SCHOOL HAS CAN -- CANCELED
ITS HOLIDAY CONCERT AND
REPLACED IT WITH AN
ANTI-BULLYING CONCERT.
PUBLIC SCHOOLS ADMIT SOME
PARENTS COMPLAINED ABOUT THE
RELIGIOUS CONTENT OF THE
SHOW.
BUT SHE DENIES THE REASON WHY
THEY ARE FORE GOING THE
FA-LA-LA'S FOR THAT REASON.
WE JUST HAD A LITTLE CHANGE AT
THAT PARTICULAR SCHOOL BECAUSE
THEY HAD A BIG INITIATIVE ON
ANTI-BULLYING.
BUT SOME TOWN RESIDENTS DON'T
SEE IT THAT WAY WITH ONE
WRITING, EVERYTHING THESE DAYS
HAS TO BE POLITICALLY
CORRECT.
WHAT IS THIS WORLD COMING TO
WHEN THIRN CANNOT PUT ON A
CHRISTMAS PLAY?
WHAT IS THE WORLD COMING TO
INDEED?
THE NEW SHOW'S THEME WILL BE
PEACE, FRIENDSHIP, KINDNESS,
BE GOOD TO YOUR FELLOW
STUDENTS AND ACCEPT
DIFFERENCES AND BE
SUPPORTIVE.
>> BOO.
>> SOMETIMES I THINK WE ARE
LOWERING THE BAR.
I WANT TO ASK YOU, HARRIS, THE
ANTI-BULLY SEMINARS ARE
BECOMING THE SECULAR
CHRISTMAS.
IT IS EXCLUSIVELY FUN FOR
CHRISTIANS.
YOU CAN'T SAY THEY ARE BAD,
AND THEY AFFECT EVERYBODY,
EXAMINE IT IS LIKE A SECULAR
REPLACEMENT.
>> ONE, THE BULLIES WIN AGAIN
IF YOU TAKE AWAY CHRISTMAS.
>> WE DID IT Y'ALL!
>> RIGHT?
I MEAN, I LIKE THE IDEA OF
TEACHING KINDNESS AND PEACE,
BUT THEN WHY WOULDN'T YOU JUST
PUT THAT PROGRAM ON IN
DECEMBER?
THEY KNOW THEY ARE NOT RIGHT
IN THIS CASE.
WHAT THEY ARE DOING IS JUST
KILLING THE PROGRAM.
THEY ARE NOT REPLACING IT.
THEY ARE KILLING IT.
THEY ARE RUNNING A PROGRAM
LATER IN JANUARY DURING THE
CELEBRATION OF MARTIN LUTHER
KING'S BIRTHDAY.
THEY WANTED A REASON TO KILL
CHRISTMAS.
THIS WAS A LITTLE PIECE THAT
KILLED ME.
INDIVIDUALS WHO OBJECTED TO
THE RELIGIOUS NATURE OF A
CHRISTMAS PROGRAM SHOULD JUST
STAY HOME.
AMEN.
WHY NOT JUST STAY HOME IF YOU
DON'T WANT YOUR KID THERE?
WHY KL CHRISTMAS FOR
EVERYBODY BECAUSE THAT'S WHAT
YOU ARE DOING.
OTHERWISE YOU WOULD SIMPLY
REPLACE IT.
>> LET'S TAKE THE FIRST STORY
AND COMPARE IT WITH THE SECOND
STORY.
YOU HAVE THE AMERICAN
GOVERNMENT SAYING YOU CAN'T
TALK ABOUT HOMOSEXUALS OR
WOMEN OR PEDOPHILES OVER
THERE.
WE WILL RESPECT THAT.
OVER HERE IN OUR COUNTRY
CHRISTMAS IS A BAD THING.
THE FACT OF THE MATTER IS
CHRISTMAS -- THE BIRTH OF
CHRIST IS HISTORICALLY
ACCURATE AND IT ACTUALLY
HAPPENED.
WHAT EVER YOU BELIEVE ABOUT
CHRIST IS A DIFFERENT THING.
IF WE ARE TOLERANT ABOUT
PEOPLE'S BELIEFS IT IS A
HISTORICALLY ACCURATE THING
THAT HAPPENED.
WHY ARE WE SO TOLERANT OF
THOSE GUYS, BUT WHEN IT COMES
TO OUR THING IT IS LIKE, WE
CAN'T DO IT.
WE ARE NOT TOLERANT.
>> IT IS NOT LIKE WE ARE
TALKING ABOUT EASTER, THE
RESURRECTION.
>> A BUNNY?
>> NO, SWEETHEART.
AND I JUST SAY SWEE HEART
BECAUSE I LIKE YOU OR I WOULD
PUNCH YOU.
>> IF IT WAS ANYBODY ELSE YOU
WOULD PUNCH HIM IN THE FACE.
>> ARE YOU RIGHT, IT IS THE
DATE ON THE CALENDAR.
>> IT IS CH RI ST-MAS.
>> EVERYBODY IS SO AFRAID OF
PISSING SOMEBODY ELSE OFF THEY
WILL RUIN IT FOR EVERYBODY.
>> I REMEMBER HAVING CHRISTMAS
PLAYS AND CELEBRATIONS ALL
THROUGH SCHOOL.
NOBODY SEEMED TO BE ANGRY
ABOUT IT.
>> AND THAT WAS THE ONLY THING
YOU EVER WEPT TO.
>> I -- EVER WENT TO.
>> I NEVER WENT TO THE CLASS.
>> SOME OF THE BIGGEST BULLIES
ARE ACTORS AND ARE MISSING OUT
IN THE CHRISTMAS PLAY.
JUST SAYING.
>> HOW MANY MORE NEED TO BE
HURT BEFORE THIS SENSELESS WAR
ON CHRISTMAS ENDS?
>> SEVEN.
>> SHERROD, YOU ARE BEING
FLIPPANT AND EVERYBODY KNOWS
IT IS 12.
>> HOLIDAYS ARE -- BILL, WERE
YOU GOING TO ANSWER IT?
>> WELL, THE MISTAKE THEY MADE
HERE BY CAN SELLING IT AND
THEN REPLACING IT WITH
SOMETHING ELSE, IF THEY JUST
CANCELED IT, A COUPLE PARENTS
WOULD HAVE BEEN LIKE -- MMM.
AND THEN THEY WOULD SAY OH
THANK GOD WE DO DON'T HAVE TO
GO TO THIS THING.
MY KID IS ANNOYING AS IT IS.
PUT A COSTUMES ON THEM THAT'S
EVEN WORSE.
AND THEN THE KIDS WHO DON'T
HAVE A ROLE AND THE PARENTS
COMPLAIN ABOUT THAT.
NO ONE IN MY SCHOOL LIKES THE
HOLIDAY STUFF.
THE KIDS DIDN'T LIKE TO DO
IT.
THE PARENTS DIDN'T LIKE TO
WATCH IT.
THE TEACHERS DIDN'T WANT TO BE
THERE.
THE ANTI-BULLYING THING IS
WORSE.
JUST CAN SELL IT AND YOU WON'T
HAVE ANY PROBLEMS.
>> IT IS AN ATTACK ON FUN, AND
IT IS REPLACING FUN WITH A
DIDACTIC HER NEST NO FUN --
HER NEST NO FUN KILLER.
WE ARE ALL AGAINST BULLYING.
WHEN YOU HAVE A SEMINAR
EVERYBODY WILL BE LISTENING
GOING, WE KNOW IT IS WRONG, WE
KNOW IT IS WRONG.
THERE IS NO REAL STORY OTHER
THAN BE NICE TO EVERYBODY.
WE GET IT.
HOLIDAYS, HOWEVER, ARE
DECISIVE AND HURTFUL.
NOT EVERYBODY CAN HAVE THE
SAME LEVEL OF FUN.
>> WE HAVE TO COME UP WITH A
NEW HOLIDAY THAT EVERYBODY IS
INCLUDED IN.
>> WHAT WOULD THAT BE?
>> EVERYBODY LIKES PILATES?
THEY HAVE A PILATES DAY.
>> IT IS HARD TO DO.
>> WE HAVE BECOME A COUNTRY OF
IDEA POLICE.
IF YOU ARE EXPOSED TO AN IDEA
YOU DON'T AGREE WITH, YOU
MIGHT GET SOMETHING.
>> BECAUSE IT IS I KILLER.
>> WE WILL HAVE NOTHING IN A
COUPLE YEARS.
>> PEOPLE PREFER NOTHING TO
SOMETHING.
ON THAT NOTE WE WILL TAKE A
BREAK.
COMING UP, IS ONE GROUP TO
BLAME FOR ALL OF OUR
PROBLEMS?
SHERROD SMALL DISCUSSES HIS
NEW BOOK, THE WORLD WOULD BE
RIGHT IF THERE WAS NO MORE
WHITE.
>> AND IT IS A MUSICAL.
BUT FIRST, CAN GOOGLE MAKE IT
HARDER TO FIND PORN?
I DON'T KNOW.
ALL OF MY SITES ARE
BOOKMARKED.
>>> IS CHRIS CHRISTIE TOO BIG
FOR A PRESIDENTIAL GIG?
THE NEW JERSEY GOVERNOR WAS
ASKED IF HIS GIRTH WOULD GET
IN THE WAY ON BARBARA WALTERS'
10 MORE FASCINATING PEOPLE
SPECIAL.
>> THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO SAY
YOU COULDN'T BE PRESIDENT
BECAUSE YOU ARE SO HEAVY.
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THEM?
>> THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
PEOPLE WATCHED ME THE LAST
COUPLE WEEKS DURING HURRICANE
SUNDAY FOR 18 DAYS.
I DON'T THINK THAT WOULD BE A
PROBLEM.
>> THAT WAS AS HARD-HITTING AS
HIS PANTS AREN'T FITTING.
LET'S CHECK IN WITH BARBARA
WALTERS' MOST INTERESTING
CAT.
TERRIBLE AND NOT FUNNY
WHATSOEVER.
SHERROD, IS CHRISTIE'S WEIGHT
WITH VOTERS OR IS THIS AN
ISSUE WITH THE MAINSTREAM
MEDIA.
>> SHOW RESPECT FOR BARBARA
WALTERS WHO KNOWS HOW TO ASK A
QUESTION.
SHE NEVER SAYS, HEY, I THINK
YOU ARE TOO FAT TO RUN.
SHE SAYS, WHAT DO YOU PEOPLE
TO PEOPLE WHO SAY --
>> THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO SAY
--
>> WHAT WOULD YOU SAY TO
THEM?
>> SHE KNOWS HOW TO ASK THE
QUESTION AND NOT P UT IT ON
HER.
I LOVE IT.
>> THIS IS A WOMAN WHO HAS
BEEN A TALK SHOW HOST FOR MANY
YEARS AND HAS AN UNUSUAL VOCAL
DELIVERY.
SHE IS ASKING A FAT GUY IF HE
SHOULD BE PRESIDENT, AND SHE
HAS BEEN A A TALK SHOW HOST OR
INTERVIEWER FOR 40 YEARS WITH
AN UNUSUAL VOCAL DELIVERY.
SEE MY POINT?
>> NO, I DON'T SEE IT AT ALL.
>> FIRST OF ALL AS A FAT GUY,
I DON'T THINK I CAN --
>> ARE YOU NOT.
>> DON'T YOU DO THAT!  DON'T
YOU DO THAT!  YOU LOOK GREAT.
>> I DON'T THINK I SHOULD -- I
DON'T THINK I SHOULD THROW
STONES.
LET'S GET PAST THE QUESTION.
THIS IS THE MOST RIDICULOUS
ANSWER CHRIS CHRISTIE HAS EVER
GIVEN IN HIS POLITICAL
CAREER.
HE IS KNOWN FORGIVING STRAIGHT
TALK.
HE IS KNOWN FOR JUST SAYING IT
AS IT IS.
AND HE GOES, BARBARA, I DON'T
KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW I'M FAT.
>> THIS IS LIKE, YOU KNOW THIS
IS ALMOST LIKE -- GAVIN HAS
SAID THIS, BUT IT IS AN
ACHIEVEMENT TO GET LARGE.
>> DOWN WHERE I AM FROM, THIS
IS SVELT.
THIS IS A PRACTICAL THING.
I SPENT FOUR MONTHS ON A BUS,
AND ONCE YOU GET SECRET
SERVICE YOU NEVER WALK.
WHATEVER HIS WEIGHT IS BEFORE
HE STARTS CAMPAIGNING, THINK
ADD 50.
>> THE SECRET SERVICE KEEP YOU
FROM WALKING?
>> LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING.
THEY PICK YOU UP FROM THE
FRONT DOOR, AND THEY TAKE YOU
TO EVENTS.
THEY PICK YOU UP AND DROP YOU
OFF AT PLANES.
YOU STOP WALKING.
>> THEY DON'T WANT YOU
APPROACHED.
LET ME ASK YOU, HARRIS, WHAT
DO YOU MAKE OF THIS?
DO YOU THINK IT WAS OFFENSIVE
FOR HER TO BRING UP HIS
WEIGHT?
>> I THINK IT WAS IRRELEVANT,
ALTHOUGH PEOPLE ARE TALKING
ABOUT IT.
I WOULD HAVE OWNED IT THEN.
I WOULD HAVE SAID, YOU KNOW,
YOU LOOK LIKE YOU'RE HUNGRY.
IS THAT A PROBLEM?
>> BILL, HERE IS MY PROBLEM.
WE ARE LOSING OUR FAT PEOPLE.
THERE ARE NONE IN THE PUBLIC
EYE.
234* THE OLD DAYS THERE WERE
FAT ROLE MODELS OR ROLL ROLE
MODELS.
EVERYBODY KNEW FAT PEOPLE.
THEY WERE EVERYWHERE, AND THEY
WERE -- JACKIE FLEA GLEE
SON -- JACKIE GLEASON.
>> FATTY ARBUCKLE.
>> HE WAS A TERRIBLE ROLE
MODEL.
>> IT IS CALLED MIKE AND
MOLLY.
LET'S WATCH A LITTLE MIKE AND
>> YOU THINK IT WAS A
LEGITIMATE QUESTION?
>> I THINK IT IS A
LEGITIMATE -- NO, I DON'T
KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW ANYONE WHO SAYS
HE CAN'T BE PRESIDENT BECAUSE
HE IS SO BIG.
I NEVER HEARD THAT.
>> PEOPLE ARE WORRIED ABOUT
HIS HEALTH.
THIS IS A GUY WHO ON THE
JERSEY BOARDWALK LAST SUMMER
BEFORE WE HAD THE AWFUL
STORMS, LAST SUMMER WAS EATING
ICE CREAM AND DONUTS AND GOT
INTO A FIGHT.
REMEMBER THAT?
>> I LOVED THAT.
HE FOLLOWED THE GUY.
>> HE DIDN'T PUT HIS ICE CREAM
DOWN WHILE HE BLESSED OUT THIS
PERSON.
>> THAT IS A GOOD POINT.
HE WORKED LIKE 20 HOURS EVERY
DAY DURING HURRICANE SANDY.
AND YET HE DID NOT LOSE A
POUND.
THIS IS DEDICATION OF A LEVEL
I HAVE NEVER SEEN.
YOU HAVE TO MULTI TASK YOUR
EATING TO SUCH A DEGREE, I
DON'T KNOW WHO YOU HE DOES
IT.
I DO KNOW HE HAS TO HAVE THE
STICKEST MOST CRUMB-FILLED
KEYBOARD IN AWFUL GOVERNMENT.
>> AND THAT'S SEXY.
>> THERE IS A SERIOUS POINT.
HE IS A LEADER THAT PEOPLE
LOOK UP TO, AND HEALTH IS AN
ISSUE.
HE AND OBAMA WALKING DOWN
TOGETHER LOOK LIKE AN
INTERRACIAL NUMBER 10.
LOOK, NBC'S "BIG LOSER" POE
LIT CAL EDITION, HUCKABEE DID
IT.
HE WAS A FAT GOVERNOR AND
STARTED RUNNING.
>> AGAIN, HEALTH WAS THE SPARK
THERE, SO I HAVE READ.
YOU KNOW WITH GOVERNOR
HUCKABEE, ONCE HE GETS HIS
SIGHTS ON SOMETHING HE WILL
FINISH IT.
MAYBE GOVENOR CHRIS STEY
DOESN'T FEEL LIKE HE NEEDS TO
DO THAT.
BUT HE SHOULD HAVE ANSWERED
THE QUESTION HONESTLY.
YOU KNOW WHAT, BARBARA, WHO
EVER YOU ARE QUOTING, I AM
FAT.
I OWN THAT.
I LOVE IT.
MOVE ON.
>> YOU KNOW WHAT I WAS
THINKING ABOUT?
HOW AWESOME IT IS TO LIE ON A
BED, AND YOU HAVE THIS REALLY
HOT, HOT DONUT, AND IT IS LIKE
ON A CONTRAPTION ABOVE YOU AND
YOU PUT IN SCOOPS OF ICE CREAM
AND IT MELTS INTO YOUR MOUTH.
IT IS ICE CREAM DRIPPING INTO
YOUR MOUTH AND ALL OVER YOUR
FACE.
>> SO YOU HAVE BEEN TO THE
GOVERNOR'S MANSION.
GREG GOT THE PRIVATE TOUR.
NOW THAT NONDISCLOSURE
AGREEMENT YOU SIGNED IS OUT
THE WINDOW.
>> IT IS AMAZING.
>> HUGH HEFNER HAS A SWING IN
HIS BEDROOM, BUT WE HAVE THE
ICE CREAM CANOPY.
>> DO YOU HAVE A COMMENT ON
THE SHOW?
E-MAIL US.
IT IS RED EYE AT FOX
NEWS.COM.
AND DO YOU HAVE ANY VIDEOS OF
YOUR ANIMAL DOING SOMETHING,
BUT NOT FALLING BECAUSE THAT'S
WRONG.
CLICK ON SUBMIT A INDIVIDUAL
YOY, AND WE MAY USE IT.
STILL TO COME, THE HALF TIME
REPORT FROM ANDY LEVY.
HE IS OUR DONUT -- HOLE.
>> IT IS SPONSORED BY ICE
SKATING, USING THE ICE SKATE
TO GLIDE OVER AN ICE COVERED
SURFACE.
THANKS, ICE SKATE SKATING.
>>> FOR THAT WE GO TO ANDY
LEVY.
I WANT TO CONGRATULATE YOU.
>> FOR LANDING THE ROLE AS
JEREMY RENNER'S STUNT DOUBLE.
IT IS A COLLEGE-AGE --
COLLEGE-AGED FILM.
>> I RUINED IT.
>> YOU KIND OF DID.
>> THANKS, SLEEVE LESS JOE.
>> I HAVE SLEEVES.
>> HE IS WORKING ON A CAR OUT
BACK.
>> HE DIDN'T KNOW WE WERE DHOG
SHOW TONIGHT.
-- WE WERE DOING THIS SHOW
TONIGHT JIE. CASUAL GREG IS
DIFFERENT THAN REGULAR GREG.
>> OKAY.
>> CASUAL GREG CAN HANG OUT
AND TALK AND RAP AFTER THE
SHOW.
>> RAP?
>> THAT'S WHAT I CALL TALKING
ABOUT EMOTIONAL AND PERSONAL
ISSUES.
>> REALLY?
>> THAT'S WHAT I DO WITH
KIDS.
>> I CALL MY OFFICE THE TREE
HOUSE.
EE HOUSE.
>> THINGS I DID ON THE BUS.
>> YOU WERE JUST GIVING THE
PROSECUTION SO MUCH
AMMUNITION.
>> LET'S GET TO IT, SHALL WE?
PROPOSED ARMY HANDBOOK WOULD
ADVISE SOLDIERS NO THE TO
SPEAK ILL OF THE TALIBAN AND
SPEAK UP FOR WOMEN'S RIGHTS.
SHERROD, YOU SAID IT IS
TELLING OUR TROOPS THEY ARE
THERE TO DO A JOB, AND THEY
SHOULD MIND THEIR BUSINESS
BEYOND THAT.
THIS IS APPLYING THE
THANKSGIVING DINNER RULES TO
AFGHANISTAN.
>> WHAT IS THE THANKSGIVING
DINNER RULES?
>> YOU DON'T TALK ABOUT
CERTAIN THINGS.
>> YOU DON'T TALK ABOUT IT.
IT IS LIKE BEING AROUND
FAMILY.
SOME THINGS YOU KEEP IN
HOUSE.
WHEN YOU HAVE OTHER PEOPLE
AROUND A THAT AIN'T FAMILY YOU
TALK REGULAR TALK.
>> WHEN YOU HAVE THE CRAZY
RACIST UNCLE AT THANKSGIVING
DINNER, IE ME, THERE ARE
CERTAIN SUBJECTS YOU DON'T
BRING UP.
>> THIS RAISES A POINT.
>> THERE IS A DIFFERENCE THANK
GIVES AND THE TALIBAN,
ALCOHOL.
>> ONE OF THE REASONS YOU
CAN'T SAY ANYTHING TO THE
TALIBAN IS THAT THEY ARE
ALWAYS SOBER WHICH MAKES THEM
MISERABLE PEOPLE.
>> WE NEED TO PUT COCAINE IN
THEIR WATER.
>> THEY HAVE DRUGS THERE
THOUGH.
>> THEY SELL OPIUM.
>> THAT'S WHAT EVERY DEALER
SAYS.
>> UNTIL THEY GET CAUGHT.
AND THEN IT IS ALL FOR
PERSONAL USE.
>> YOU SAID PART OF THE REASON
WE ARE THERE IS TO SHARE OUR
VALUES.
AND TO WIN HEARTS AND MINDS.
IT JUST DOESN'T SEEM TO BE
WORKING.
>> THAT'S NOT THE POINT.
THE POINT IS THEY DON'T WANT
IT TO HAPPEN AT ALL.
IF YOU BLOCK IT IT DOESN'T
HAVE A CHANCE TO HAPPEN.
WE DON'T KNOW THAT FOR
CERTAIN.
IT IS ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE FOR
PEOPLE TO BE IN EACH OTHER'S
COMPANY FOR THE AMOUNT OF
YEARS THAT OUR TROOPS HAVE
BEEN ON THE GROUND IN THAT
COUNTRY AND NOT HAVE SHARED
SOME SORT OF CULTURAL BACK AND
FORTH.
AND IN A VERY GOOD, POSITIVE
WAY.
I AM AN OPTIMIST, BUT I HAVE A
DAD WHO SERVED.
I UNDERSTAND THAT WHEN YOU
HAVE BOOTS ON THE GROUND FOR
THAT LONG THERE WILL BE SOME
SHARED EXPERIENCES.
AND WITH ALL PRAYERS, I JUST
HOPE THAT WE CAN RUB OFF THE
GOOD STUFF ON EACH OTHER.
THEY ARE HUMAN, SO THEY HAVE
STUFF THEY CAN SHARE WITH US
TOO.
AMEN, CAN I GET AN AMEN?
>> THE FLIP SIDE IS WHEN YOU
HAVE BOOTS ON THE GROUND FOR
SO LONG THE PEOPLE START TO
RECENT YOU.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> THERE IS ALWAYS A SEGMENT
OF THE POPULATION THAT CAN
OPEN THAT DOOR.
IF YOU BLOCK IT, IF YOU TELL
OUR TROOPS THAT YOU FORBID IT,
THEY WILL FOLLOW THAT
COMMAND.
>> YOU SAID IF THIS WILL KEEP
OUR SOLDIERS SAFE, THEN YOU
ARE FOR IT WHICH I AGREE
WITH.
BUT IS THE FACT THAT WE NEED
SOMETHING LIKE THIS, DOES THAT
MEAN IT IS TIME TO GET OUT?
>> I THINK THAT IS THE
PROBLEM.
LIKE I SAID BEFORE WE ARE
MAKING OUR TROOPS INTO
DIPLOMATS.
>> BILL, YOU WERE CORRECT WHEN
YOU SAID THIS IS NOT JUST
ABOUT THE AT THAT .
THIS IS ABOUT THE PEOPLE WHO
ARE SUPPOSED TO BE ON OUR SIDE
EVEN THOUGH IT SEEMS LIKE A
LOT OF THEM ROBERT.
>> AS PATRICK SAID, BOY THIS
IS FUNNY.
>> PATRICK, IT IS LIKE JAZZ.
SOMETIMES THE HUMOR IS IN WHAT
I DON'T SAY.
>> I AM LAUGHING ON THE
INSIDE.
>> THAT'S A SWEET, SENTIMENTAL
THOUGHT.
>> THAT'S CRAP IS WHAT IT IS.
HARRISON, CENTER FOREARM ME
LESSONS LEARNED, WHAT IT DOES
IS RAPIDLY COLLECTS AND
ANALYZES AND ARCHIVES THE
OPERATIONAL RECORDS IN ORDER
TO FACILITATE INITIATIVES AND
CONDUCT FOCUS, KNOWLEDGE AND
FORMS THE ARMY AND ENABLES THE
OPERATIONALLY BASED INGNAW
GRACIOUS AND INTEGRATION
THROUGHOUT THE ARMY AND IN THE
JIM ENVIRONMENT.
>> AND ALL YOU REALLY NEED TO
KNOW --
>> WHY DO YOU HATE THE
MILITARY, GREG?
WHY DO YOU HATE THE MILITARY
AND MILITARY PROGRAMS THAT ARE
SET UP TO MAKE OUR ARMY
BETTER?
WHY SIR?
>> WOW.
>> HE IS THINKING ABOUT IT.
>> THAT'S THE CENTER THAT
WROTE THE JOURNAL.
THE ONLY BUDS MAN IS TRYING TO
SHOW US.
>> YOU NEED TO DRILL DOWN,
HARRIS.
>> IT IS A NEWSCHANNEL.
>> YOU REALIZE THE HOST IS NO
LONGER TALKING.
>> I WOULD SAY THAT WAS MY
SECONDARY PURPOSE.
BUT IT WAS MY PRIMARY.
>> JOB WELL DONE.
>> THEY REPLACE THE CHRISTMAS
CONCERT WITH ANTI-BULLYING
PROGRAM.
HARRIS, YOU SAID THE BULLIES
WIN AGAIN IF THEY TAKE AWAY
CHRISTMAS.
THEY ARE NOT TAKING AWAY
THEY ARE CAN SELLING A
CONCERT.
>> THEY ARE SAYING THEY ARE
NOT GOING HAVE IT THAT WAY.
THEY DIDN'T REPLACE IT.
A MONTH LATER THEY ARE GOING
TO DO THE BULLY PROGRAM.
IT IS NOT LIKE THEY PHYSICALLY
PUT SOMETHING IN PLACE.
I GUESS YOU WOULDN'T ENJOY AN
ANTI-BULLYING PROGRAM.
>> TO ME IT IS ANOTHER WAY
THEY WILL DESTROY THE ARTS IN
SCHOOLS.
MORE THAN A CHRISTMAS PLAY IS
A PLAY.
ONE OF MY FAVORITE TIMES IN
SCHOOL.
GREECE, WE DID GREECE IN
THE -- GREASE, WE DID GREECE
-- GREASE IN MY CLASS.
AND I WAS KINICKI.
>> CAN YOU DO THAT?
>> I NEED THE WIG.
>> I PLAYED RIZZO AND I DIDN'T
NEED THE WIG OF THE.
>> YOU'RE WELCOME.
>> PATRICK, I DIDN'T REALLY
UNDERSTAND OR AGREE WITH YOUR
ARGUMENT, YOU SAID SOMETHING
ABOUT BECAUSE JOE SUCCESS WAS
A HISTORICAL FIGURE.
BUT THAT HAS NOTHING TO DO
WITH WHAT CHRISTMAS
CELEBRATES.
IT IS CELEBRATING THE BIRTH OF
THE SON OF GOD.
>> BUT THE POINT IS, THERE IS
A HISTORICALLY RELEVANT
COMPONENT TO THAT FOR
NONCHRISTIANS.
PEOPLE WHO DO NOT CLAIM TO BE
CHRISTIANS OR ARE NOT
CHRISTIANS THEIR EYES WILL NOT
BURN OUT OF THEIR HEAD BY
WATCHING SOMETHING THAT DOES
THAT.
>> JESUS IN A MANGER.
>> BUT THE ENTIRE POINT OF
CHRISTMAS IS THAT JESUS IS THE
SON OF GOD.
IT IS NOT THAT HE WAS A MAN.
>> THE POINT OF CHRISTMAS,
JESUS THE SON OF GOD WAS BORN
THAT DAY.
>> RIGHT, EXACTLY.
THE SON OF GOD.
I'M CONFUSED.
>> YOU ARE TRYING TO HAVE A
FIGHT ABOUT JESUS CHRIST.
>> I AM NOT HAVING A FIGHT
ABOUT IT.
I THINK IT IS DISINGENERAL
WISE TO PRETEND THAT CHRISTMAS
IS ABOUT THE BIRTH OF A
HISTORICAL FIGURE.
>> I AM NOT SAYING THAT AT
ALL.
FOR THE PEOPLE THAT ARE
ARGUING AGAINST THIS AND AS
ONLY YOUR RELIGIOUS THING, I
THINK THAT IS DISINGENERAL
WISE IS THEY KNOW NOBODY CAN
LOOK AT CHRISTMAS BECAUSE OF
THE BIRTH OF CHRIST.
>> IT IS A RELIGIOUS HOLIDAY.
>> BUT IT IS SOMETHING PEOPLE
CAN LEARN FROM.
IT IS NOT IMPOSING VALUES ON
ANYBODY.
>> I HEAR WHAT YOU ARE TRYING
TO SAY.
ANDY, THIS IS SOMETHING YOU
CAN LEARN FROM.
DO YOU CATCH MY MEANING?
WHY DON'T YOU COME TO SERVICE
WITH ME THIS YEAR.
>> IT IS NOT TOO LATE.
>> SHERROD, YOU CAN'T HAVE A
PILLA TEASE DAY.
>> THAT WAS PONTIOUS PILOT.
CHRIS CHRISTIE TELLS BARBARA
WALTERS THAT HE IS NOT TOO
FAT.
I THOUGHT IT WAS FANTASTIC
WHEN SHE SAID THERE ARE PEOPLE
WHO SAY.
BUT OTHERS SAY THAT IS A
CHEESY JOURNALISTIC PRACTICE.
>> IT STILL WORKS.
THEY ARE STILL MAKING THE BIG
MONEY.
>> I AGREE.
>> HARRIS, YOU SAID IF
GOVERNOR HUCK UH KEY -- HUCK
UH BE WANTS TO GET HIS SIGHTS
ON SOMETHING HE FINISHES IT.
COULDN'T YOU SAY THE SAME
THING ABOUT GOVERNOR CHRISTIE
AND A BUCKET OF CHICKEN?
>> I DON'T KNOW WHAT HE LIKES
OTHER THAN DONUTS AND ICE
CREAM.
IF HE DECIDED HE WANT TO DO
SOMETHING ABOUT HIS WEIGHT, HE
WOULD DO IT.
>> YOU ARE PROBABLY RIGHT.
>> HE SHOULD HAVE SAID THIS.
I AM FINE THE WAY I AM.
IF I GET TO A POINT WHERE I
CAN CHANGING IT, I CHANGE IT.
HE NEEDS TO REFER TO HIMSELF
AS 2PHAT WHERE THE 2 IS THE
NUMBER AND THE PHAT WITH A
P-H.
YOU GET THE TWO CHAINS AND THE
OLD SCHOOL PEOPLE BECAUSE YOU
HAVE PHAT WITH A P-H.
>> THE KIDS WANT TO CALL THEM
FATTY BOOM BOOM.
>> IT WAS NOT THE FACT OF HIS
WEIGHT, BUT THE ANSWER TO THE
QUESTION.
I DON'T KNOW HOW IT GOT THIS
WAY.
>> IS IT NOT POSSIBLE HE WEPT
TO BED ON A THURSDAY AND WAS
IN PERFECT SHAPE AND THEN WOKE
UP FRIDAY AND WAS HUGE.
>> YOU THINK IT IS IMPOSSIBLE,
BUT IT DOESN'T MAKE IT
IMPOSSIBLE.
I HAVE SEEN WEIRDER THINGS.
>> IS THAT WHAT HAPPENED TO
THAT SHIRT YOU ARE WEAR ?G.
>> THEN YOU TURNED THAT
MICHAEL J FOX FROM 1987?
>> YEP.
>> ARE WE DONE HERE?
MOMENTUM KILLER 2012.
COMING UP, WHERE DO KITTENS
COME FROM?
NOT A STORY, JUST SOMETHING
LOU DOBBS SENT ME.
BUT FIRST, IS FACEBOOK MAKING
PEOPLE FATTER?
IT IS ACCORDING TO FACEBOOK IS
MAKING PEOPLE FATTER.COM.
THAT'S WHERE I GET ALL MY
NEWS.
>>> WILL IT BE A THORN FOR
FANS OF PORN?
GOOGLE HAS MODIFIED ITS FILTER
TO MAKE IT HARDER TO STUMBLE
ON TO SEXY, SEXY CONTENT
ACCIDENTALLY.
WE HAVE ALL BEEN THERE.
IF YOU ARE LOOKING FOR ADULT
CON AT THE PRESENT TIME YOU
CAN FIND IT WITHOUT HAVING TO
CHANGE THE DEFAULT SETTING.
YOU MAY JUST NEED TO BE MORE
EXPLICIT IN YOUR QUERY IF YOUR
SEARCH TERMS ARE AM AMBIGUOUS
-- AM AMBIGUOUS?
>> THAT'S ONE OF MY
DAUGHTERS.
>> AM AMBIGUOUS IS KINKY.
LET'S DISCUSS IN THE --
>> LIGHTNING
ROOOOOOOUUUUUUNNNNNDDDD.
LIGHTNING ROUND.
[APPLAUSE].
>> YOU FIND PORN BY ACCIDENT
EVERY DAY.
>> I FIND THAT -- I FIND IT
BEHIND THE HIGH SCHOOL IN THE
WOODS.
>> THOSE WERE THE GOOD OLD
DAYS.
>> I THINK THAT WAS GOOD.
BACK THEN -- IT WAS HARD TO
FIND PORN.
IT WAS LIKE HE WAS REWARDED IF
HE FOUND IT.
>> YOU CAN STUMBLE ON TO IT.
>> THE NEXT THING YOU KNOW YOU
HAVE BOOBIES ON THE SCREEN.
>> PATRICK, ACCIDENTAL PORN
HAPPENS, BUT WE MAKE A JOKE,
BUT ISN'T IT A BIGGER PROBLEM
THAT IS AVAILABLE AT ALL
TIMES?
>> WELL, YES.
THIS IS A GREAT THING -- TRUE
STORY.
NOT A JOKE.
I HAVE THREE DAUGHTERS.
THEY WANTED FOR CHRISTMAS BIG
TEDDY BEARS.
>> OH MY GOD.
>> I MADE THE BAD MISTAKE OF
GOOGLING BIG BEARS.
LET ME TELL YOU WHAT COMES UP
WHEN YOU PUT IN BIG BEARS.
>> DID YOU SEE A GUY NAMED
BILLY WHO WAS 47?
>> THAT WAS A UNION RALLY.
>> YOU DRESS THEM LIKE VILLAGE
PEOPLE AND HAVE THEM DO THIS
YOU HAVE BIG BEARS.
NOBODY NEEDS TO SEE THAT
EVER.
THANK YOU, GOOGLE.
>> I FIND IT QUITE
ENTERTAINING.
I GET FASHION TIPS FROM
THERE.
>> I BROWSE THROUGH.
>> DO YOU EVER BELIEVE PEOPLE
FIND PORN BY ACCIDENT?
>> I KNOW CHILDREN HAVE FOUND
IT BY ACCIDENT.
ABSOLUTELY.
SO IN MY HOUSEHOLD WHERE I
HAVE A SIX-YEAR-OLD AS OF THIS
WEEK AND A THREE-YEAR-OLD I
PUT CONTROLS ON EVERYTHING.
HAVE I TO NOT LET THEM PLAY
WITH MY IPAD UNTIL I HAVE
TURNED ON THE YOU ARE A PORT
MODE.
>> BUT THEY ARE SAVY AND THEY
CAN GO THROUGH IT.
>> AND THERE ARE THINGS THEY
MIGHT PUT IN -- IT IS
AMAZING.
MY THREE-YEAR-OLD SAYS TO ME
THE OTHER DAY BECAUSE SHE IS
HEARING IT ON THE RADIO NOW
AND I HAVE TO BE CONSCIOUS
FROM THE GINGHAM STYLE VIDEO
SHE'S SEXY AND SHE KNOW
ITSELF.
CHILDREN LEARN.
>> AND ANY SEARCH TERMS THAT
ARE ANYWAY, SHAPE OR FORM
RELATED WILL BRING SOMETHING
UP THAT THEY WILL NEVER, EVER,
EVER SEE.
>> GOOGLE POPSICLE.
SEE WHAT COMES UP ON.
>> WELL NOW I HAVE TO.
>> YOU MADE THE STATEMENT A
FEW MOMENTS AGO THAT ALL OF US
HAVE BEEN THERE.
NOT EVERYBODY AT THIS TABLE
HAS BEEN THERE.
>> BILL HASN'T BEEN THERE.
HIS PORN CONSISTS OF DRAWINGS
THAT HE DOES ON THE CARDBOARD
BOX HE SLEEPS IN.
>> I HAVE GOTTEN RID OF THE
BLOGGERS.
LET ME TELL YOU THE REASON GOD
MADE IT.
WHY HE MADE A LAPTOP AND
GOOGLE.
>> I AM WATCHING TV.
GABRIELLE REECE, I WONDER --
GABRIELLE REECE, NUDE, OH YES,
1988.
THAT IS WHY COMPUTERS EXIST.
THIS IS WHY I GO HOME EVERY
NIGHT.
I DON'T HAVE A GIRLFRIEND.
BUT HAVE I MY GOOGLE IMAGE
SEARCH AND I WANT TO KNOW IF
THERE WAS A TOPLESS SEEN IN
1989.
>> THE MOST IMPORTANT THING IS
I MET GABBY REECE.
SHE WAS THE OLYMPIC VOLLEYBALL
PLAYER.
>> SHOOT, I AM THINKING OF
SOMEBODY ELSE.
>> SHE DID POSE NUDE.
SHE DID POSE NUDE.
LOOK IT UP, OH WAIT YOU
CAN'T.
GO TO BING.
BAD MOVE ON YOUR PART,
GOOGLE.
>>> WE HAVE TO TAKE A BREAK.
DON'T LEAVE NOW.
THERE IS MORE TO TALK ABOUT I
THINK, I HOPE.
>>> NEW STUDIES LINKED
FACEBOOK TO OVER EATING AND
OVER SPENDING.
IT HAD A HIGHER BODY MASS
INDEX AND CREDIT CARD DEBT.
IT CAN LEAD TO LESS
SELF-CONTROL IN OTHER AREAS OF
YOUR LIFE.
PRETEND IT MAKES SENSE,
EVERYBODY.
SHERROD, DOES THIS MAKE SENSE,
AND SHOULD MARK ZUCKERBERG BE
ARRESTED?
>> I ALWAYS SAID HE SHOULD BE
ARRESTED.
>> AND YOU ARE OVER EATING,
YOU ARE OVER SPENDING BECAUSE
ARE YOU BUYING FOOD YOU DON'T
NEED.
>> I GUESS.
>> OR IS THIS A FOOLISH
STORY.
>> PATRICK, YOU THINK THIS IS
TRUE?
THE WHOLE INTERNET IN
GENERAL?
YOU ARE SITTING THERE, OF
COURSE YOU WILL GAIN WEIGHT.
>> I THINK NOW WE KNOW WHY
CHRIS CHRISTIE IS FAT.
OBAMA SPENDS TOO MUCH, AND
THAT EXPLAINS BOTH OF THOSE.
>> HARRIS?
>> THAT'S GOOD FOR ME.
>> WELL THIS TRULY HAS BECOME
A BAD STORY TOO.
>> I DON'T THINK I KNOW
ANYBODY WHO TROLLS FACEBOOK.
WHO DOES THAT?
>> YOU GO ON AND SEE WHAT
SOMEBODY SAYS AND GET OFF.
>> YOU POST YOUR BEHIND THE
SCENES WITH GREG GUTFELD AND
THE GANG PICTURES.
>> BY THE WAY WE HAD SLEPT
PICTURES OF THE -- EXCELLENT
PICTURES OF THE BUS TOUR ON
FACEBOOK.
>> I AM GETTING FAT JUST
THINKING ABOUT IT.
>> THE DISTURBING THING IN
THIS STORY IS PEOPLE GET THIS
ARTIFICIAL SENSE OF
SELF-ESTEEM BY BEING ON
FACEBOOK.
IF YOU ARE GETTING SELF-ESTEEM
FROM FACEBOOK, YOU MAY NEED TO
TALK TO SOMEBODY.
>> THAT'S A GREAT IDEA FOR
TEENAGE GIRLS OUT THERE.
IF THEY WANT TO GET THEIR
FRIEND OR FRENEMY THEY GO ON
FACEBOOK PAGE AND LIKE, LIKE,
LIKE, LIKE.
OH THAT'S GREAT.
ANOTHER DORITO.
THE NEXT THING YOU KNOW TWENTY
POUNDS LATER AND NO BOYFRIEND
AND GREASY SKIN TO BOOT.
THINK ABOUT IT.
>> IN ANOTHER LIFE YOU WERE A
MEAN GIRL.
>> I DEFINITELY WAS.
>> AND IN ANOTHER LIFE I MEAN
THREE YEARS AGO.
WE HAVE TO TAKE A BREAK.
HE DID.
HE HAD SURGERY THREE YEARS
AGO.
HE WAS A MEAN GIRL.
POST GAME WRAP UP.
I HOPE HE READS FROM A BOOK.
>>> SEE YOU BACK HERE AT 5:00
P.M. EASTERN.
AND THEN O'REILLY AT 8:00 P.M.
WITH REMI SPENCER.
WHO IS THAT?
>> BACK TO TV'S ANDY LEVY FOR
THE POST GAME WRAP UP.
>> THANKS.
>> HOW IS THAT SHOW ON THE
WEEKEND GOING?
>> WE CONTINUE TO BE NUMBER
ONE IN OUR TIME SLOT IN ALL OF
CABLE.
WE ARE HAPPY, FOX REPORT
WEEKEND 7:00 P.M. EASTERN AND
4:00 P.M. PACIFIC, BE THERE.
>> OUTSTANDING.
PATRICK, WHERE IS CAMILLA?
>> GO PAST ATLANTA AND HIT
FLORIDA AND BACK UP AND FIND
TO WHERE AND TURN RIGHT.
>> IT SOUNDS LIKE MY LIFE.
>> WOW.
>> IS THAT A PERSON OR A TOWN