PRIME GERALDO WILL DO SPECIALS
AND JANINE PIRO WILL BE DOING
STUFF.
STAY WITH FOX NUSE CHANNEL
THROUGHOUT THE THE WEEKEND.
I AM SORRY I HAVE TO REPORT IT
HORRIBLE STORY SPOUT OFF ABOUT
THE FACTOR.
OREILLY NEWS.COM.
WORD OF THE DAY.
NO BILLINGS WHEN RUNNING THE
FACTOR.
I AM BILL O'REILLY.
REMEMBER THE SPIN HERE.
WE ARE DEFINITELY LOOKING OUT
FOR YOU.
THIS IS A FOX NUSE ALERT.
12 HOURS REMOVED FROM AN
UNTHINKABLE TRAGEDY IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT WHERE WE
KNOW THAT 28 PEOPLE ARE DEAD
THEM CHILDREN AND 7 OF THEM
ADULTS AND ONE OF THEM THE
SHOOTER.
A 911 CALL CAME FROM THE
SCHOOL REPORTS OF A SHOOTER
INSIDE.
LOCAL AND STATE POLICE
IMMEDIATELY RESPONDED AND WHAT
THEY FOUND INSIDE DESCRIBED BY
POLICE AS HORRIFIC.
WE OBTAINED THE AUDIO TAPES
WHILE THE TRAGEDY UNFOLD.
>>> CALLER INDICATED SOMEONE
SHOOT NEGLIGENT BUILDING.
IT IS THE FRONT CLASS.
WE HAVE MULTIPLE WEAPONS AND
ONE RIFLE AND A SHOT GUN.
WE NEED AMBULANCES HERE APAP.
>>> THE SHOOTER IS 20 YEAR OLD
ADAM LANZA, HIS MOTHER IS A
TEACHER AT SANDY HOOK.
REPORTEDLY KILLED IN HER HOME
BY LANSA BEFORE THE ASSAULT ON
THE SCHOOL.
POLICE ARE QUESTIONING HIS
BROTHER RYAN WHO WAS
MISTAKENLY THOUGHT TO BE THE
SHOOTER.
POLICE ARE IN THE HORRIBLE
TASK OF IDENTIFYING THE DEAD.
IT WILL BE A LENGTHY PROCESS
AND LIKELY TAKE UNTIL TOMORROW
MORNING.
IT IS IT A FLUID SITUATION
WITH CRUCIAL PIECES OF
INFORMATION THAT CONTINUED TO
EMERGE AND RICK LEAVENTHAL
REPORTED FOR FOX ALL DAY.
RICK, WITH THE LATEST.
NSHAWN ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS ARE
NOT SUPPOSED TO BE CRIME
SCENES BUTHAT IS WHAT IS
HAPPENING IN SANDY HOOK.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER AND TEEMS
OF INVESTIGATORS ARE
COLLECTING EVIDENCE AND GOING
THROUGH THE GRUESOME TASK OF
IDENTIFYING THE BODIES OF 27
VICTIMS INCLUDING THE SHOOTER
WHO SHOT HIMSELF AFTER KILLING
6 ADULTS AND TWEPT KIDS INSIDE
OF THAT ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE ARE TOLD BY INVESTIGATORS
AND FEDERAL LAW ENFORCEMENT
SOURCES THAT THE SHOOTER ADAM
LANZA KILLED HIS MOTHER IN THE
HOME THEY SHARED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT THIS MORNING AND
THEN TOOK THREE WEAPONS THAT
SHE OWNED.
A GLOCK AND HANDGUN AND RIFLE
AND WENT TO THE SCHOOL DRIVING
HER CAR.
THE SCHOOL WHERE SHE
APPARENTLY WORKED AS A
SUBSTITUTE TEACHER.
HE GAINED ENTRANCE THROUGH THE
SECURITY AND THEN OPENED FIRE.
WE KNOW THAT THE POLICE
RESPONDED.
YOU HEARD THE AND THEY CALLED
IN REENFORCEMENTS AND THOSE
OFFICERS DIDN'T WASTE TIME.
THEY GOT ALL OF THE KIDS AND
SURVIVORS OUT OF THE SCHOOL
AND MOVED THEM TO A NEARBY
FIRE HOUSE THAT WAS SET AS A
STAGING AREA AND THAT IS WHERE
THE FRANTIC PARENTS WERE
DIRECTED TO TAKE THEIR
CHILDREN AND GET THEM HOME
SAFELY, SEAN.
>>> ONE .
REACHERS WENT ON RECORD.
THE SCHOOL HAD ADDED NEW
SECURITY THAT YOU HAD TO BE
BUZZED IN THE SCHOOL AND IT
WAS AT THAT POINT THE SHOOTER
WENT TO THE ADMINISTRATION AND
WHAT WE LEARNED IT WAS DURING
MORNING ANNOUNCEMENTS SOMEBODY
KEPT UP THE ANNOUNCEMENTS AND
THAT SERVED AS A WARNING AND A
LOT OF OTHER STORE STORSE OF
HEROISM INCLUDING THE
CUSTODIAN AND TEACHERS WHAMPT
HAVE YOU HEARD ON THE GROUND
TODAY.
>>> WE HAVE HEARD THAT
CHILDREN AND ADULTS AND
SCHOOLS HEARD SCREENS OVER THE
LOUD SPEAKER SYSTEM AS IT WAS
UPFOLDING BECAUSE THEY CAME
OVER THE SPEAKERS AND THE
CHILDREN AND TEACHERS HEARD
GUN SHOTS IN THE SCHOOL AND
MANY OF THEM TOOK COVER AND
LOCKED THEMSELVES IN
CLASSROOMS AND OTHERS RAN FOR
THE EXITS AND ONE GUN BOY SIX
YEARS OLD WATCHING HIS TEACHER
SHOT AND RUNNING FOR SAFETY
OUT OF THE CLASSROOM.
>>> TOOK HIS FREPPEDS WITH
HIM.
WE DON'T KNOW AGAIN HOW THE
SHOOTER GOT IN WHETHER THEY
BUZZED HIM BECAUSE THEY
RECOGNIZED HIM OR HE
CIRCUMVEPTED SECURITY, SEAN.
RICK, WE'LL BE CHECKING IN
THROUGHOUT THE NIGHT JOINING
ME IS CONNECTICUT STATE
REPRESENTATIVE JOHN FRY IS
WITH US AND HIS TWO NIECES AND
NEFEW WERE AT THE SCHOOL.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US
TONIGHT.
A COMMUNITY OF 27,000 PEOPLE
FAIRLY WELL TO DO MILES
NORTHEAST OF THE NEW YORK
CITY.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT THE
COMMUNITY AND WHAT YOU KNOW
FROM YOUR NIECES AND NEFEWS.
>>> SEAN, THANKS, IT IS A
GREAT TOWN HERE.
I CAN'T STOP THINKING ABOUT
LAST NIGHT, LAST NIGHT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY HAD A HOLIDAY
CONCERT THAT I ATTENDED.
MY NIECE WAS PART OF THE CHOIR
AND I THINK BACK TO THE
HUNDRED KIDS ON THE STAGE AND
THEIR FAMILIS AND SIBBLINGS
RUNNING THROUGHOUT THE
AUDITORIUM AND 12 HOURS LATER
THIS TRAGEDY OCCURRED.
>>> YEAH.
>>> OBVIOUSLY, HAVE YOU SPOKEN
TO ANY OTHER PEOPLE IN TOWN
AND STORIES THAT WE HAVE BEEN
HEARING INCLUDING THE
CUSTODIAN AND A TEACHER ON
TAPE THAT I WILL SHOW IN A
SECOND AND THE LENGTHS THAT
PEOPLE WENT TO PROTECT THE
CHILDREN WAS AMAZING.
>>> IT WAS INCREDIBLE.
I KNOW ONE OF MY NIECES WAS IN
THE LIBRARY.
AND THEY WERUSHERED BOO A
CLOSEST TO PROTECT THEM.
MY SISTER DID SOMETHING WHICH
I DON'T THINK I COULD HAVE
DONE.
SHE WAS ON THE WAY TO THE
SCHOOL AND THERE WERE FIVE OR
FOUR BOYS ALL IN FIRST GRADE
RUNNING UP QUITE A DISTANCE
FROM THE FIRE HOUSE AND SHE
STOPPED AND PICKED THEM UP AND
NOT KNOWING WHAT WAS GOING ON
AND ONE OF THE BOYS SAID THERE
WAS SOMEONE WITH A GUN TRYING
TO KILL THEM AND IN THE SCHOOL
AND SHE CALLED THE SCHOOL AND
THE POLICE DEPARTMENT AND SHE
STAYED WITH THEM.
THEY HAD EMPTIED OUT AND
STAYED WITH THEM NOT KNOWING
THE FATE OF HER OWN THREE KIDS
IN THE SCHOOL.
>>> JUST SENSELESS EVIL AND
OUR THOUGHTS AND PRAYERS.
I HOPE YOU KNOW FROM THE
COUNTRY ARE WITH YOUR
COMMUNITY TONIGHT, SIR.
STATE REPRESENTATIVE FRY,
THANK YOU FOR JOINING ME.
WE GO BACK LIVE TO NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT WHERE BILL HAMMER
IS STANDING BY TO GIVE US DEOF
THE LATEST TRAGEDY.
BILL.
>>> SEAN, THE STORY IS NOT
EVEN 12 HOURS.
WE WERE LIVE 10:15 EASTERN
TIME WHEN THE NEWS JUST
STARTED TO COME ACROSS THE
WIRE.
AND FRANKLY AT THE TIME, WE
WERE TOLD ONE PERSON WAS SHOT
IN THE FOOT AND TREATED IN THE
LOCAL HOSPITAL.
THERE LITTLE NUSE AFTER THAT
AND THAT WENT ON FOR A
CONSIDERABLE AMOUNT OF TIME.
IT WAS 45 MINUTES TO AN HOUR
WHEN WE LEARNED THE DETAILS WE
GO BACK AND PIECE TOGETHER IN
THE MIND.
THERE WERE NO OTHER INJURIES.
THERE WERE JUST DEAD BODIES
INDEED OF THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
AND THE POLICE WERE ABSORBING
THE INFORMATION AND GOING ROOM
TO ROOM AND TRYING TO MAKE
SURE THE KILLER AND GUNMAN WAS
ACCOUNTED FOR AND THOUGH ONE
ELSE WAS INSIDE .
MANY OF THE CHILDREN WERE TOLD
TO CLOSE THEIR EYES AND RUN TO
GET OUT OF THE BUILDING AND
MAKE SURE THEY DIDN'T LOOK
AROUND THE SURROUNDINGS WHERE
THEY WERE.
I SPOKE TO A WOMAN WHOYCE
DAUGHTER IS OKAY.
THEY WERE LED OUT OF THE BACK
DOOR OF THE SCHOOL TO MAKE
SURE THEY DID NOT PASS BY ANY
OF THE DEAD CHILDREN WHO WERE
LYING THERE IN THE CLASSROOMS
WHERE THEY HAD GONE TO SCHOOL
HERE.
THESE STORIES ARE JUST SO
CHILLING, SEAN.
AND WHEN YOU THINK.
WE ARE LEARNING ABOUT THIS
NEWS FOR THE FIRST TIME.
IT JUST BLOYS YOUR MIND THE
LEVEL OF EVIL THAT ROLLED
THROUGH THE TOWN TODAY.
>>> I DON'T THINK I COULD SAY
IT ANY BETTER THAN THAT, BILL.
THE IDEA THAT THE KIDS WERE
TOLD CLOSE YOUR EYES AS THEY
WALKED THEM OUT.
THREE STORIES STRUCK ME TODAY
THAT CAME TO PASS.
THE SIX YEAR JUST
MENTIONED AS THE SHOOTER WAS
SHOOTING, HE GRABBED HER
FRIENDS AND RAN OUT OF THE
CLASSROOM AND CUSTOD DAN
RUNNING UP AND DOWN THE HALLS
AND WARNING PEOPLE.
AND A TEACHER, NUMEROUS
STORIES OF TEACHERS HIDING
KIDS IN CLOSESTS AND LOCKING
DOORS AND PUTTING THEM IN THE
LAVATORIES AND ONE WAS
INTERVIEWED BY ABC EARLIER
TONIGHT.
>>> I TOOK ONE OF THE STUDENTS
ON TOP OF THE TOILEST.
I KNEW TO GET IN THERE AND YOU
WILL BE ALL RIGHT.
AND I PULLED THE BOOK SHELF
AND WE WERE BARRICADED IN
THAT.
>>> DUTELL THEM TO BE QUIET.
DID YOU WORRY.
I TOLD THEM TO BE QUIET.
AND BE ABSOLUTELY QUIET.
I WAS SO AFRAID IF HE HEARD US
AND START SHOOTING THE DOOR .
WE HAVE TO BE ABSOLUTELY QUIET
AND I SAID.
THERE ARE BAD GUYS AND WE NEED
TO WAIT FOR THE GOOD GUYS.
>>> I JUST WANTED US TO BE
OKAY.
AND I WAS SO, SO SADDENED THAT
THERE ARE PEOPLE IN THIS
SITUATION THAT ARE NOT OKAY.
AND MY HEART GOES OUT TO
ANYONE WHO KNEW THEM.
AND WAS PART OF THEIR LIVES.
I CAN'T IMAGINE.
>>> IT IS HARD TO COME TO
GRIPS WITH.
YOU CALLED THIS EVIL AND THE
PARENTS, I AM UPON SURE MANY
BOUGHT CHRISTMAS GIFTS FOR
THEIR LITTLE CHILDREN AND NOW
PLANNING FUNERALS AND
CHRISTMAS EVE AND CHRISTMAS
DAY ARE GOING TO COME AND THEY
ARE NOT GOING TO HAVE THEIR
KIDS HOME.
>>> SEAN, A FEW OF THE THINGS
WE ARE LEARNING JUST NOW ABOUT
THE VICTIMS IT IS THE NEXT
WAVE IN THE STORY.
YOU KNOWLEDGE -- THINK IT IS
SAD NOW.
HANG ON.
WE'LL PLETE THE PEOPLE KILLED
INSIDE OF THE BUILDING.
WE ARE TOLD THE PRINCIPAL HAD
BEEN IN THE SCHOOL DISTRICT
FOR YEARS.
AGE FREN.
SHE HAD TWO DAUGHTERS AND
THREE STEP DAUGHTERS AND
LEAVING ALL OF THEM BEHIND AND
GEORGE, A TEACHER IN THE
DISTRICT AS WELL TOMORROW
MORNING AT 8:00 EASTERN TIME
WE EXPECT THE STATE POLICE TO
GIVE POSITIVE IDENTIFICATION
TO THE BODIES INSIDE OF THE
BUILDING.
WHEN YOU ARE FIVE YEARS OLD,
10 OR 11 DAYS FROM CHRISTMAS.
YOU BELIEVE THAT SANTA CLAUS
WILL BE IN YOUR HOUSE.
AND TODAY, THE DEVIL CAME TO
THE TOWN AND THIS TOWN HAS TO
LIVE WITH THIS FOR THE REST OF
THE THEIR LIVES.
>>> BILL, THANK YOU FOR BEING
WITH US.
AND THIS IS THE SECOND
DEADLIEST SHOOTING IN U.S.
HISTORY.
THIS INVESTIGATION IS
UNDERWAY.
A SOURCE TOLD THE AP MORE THAN
TWO GUNS WERE FOUND INSIDE OF
THE SCHOOL.
AND WE'LL UPDATE YOU ON THAT.
WE'LL WALK THROUGH THE DAYS
AHEAD AS WE CONTINUE OUR
COVERAGE ON THE FOX NEWS
CHANNEL.
[ Male Announcer ]
RED LOBSTER'S
HITTING THE STREETS
TO TELL REAL PEOPLE ABOUT
OUR NEW 15 UNDER $15 MENU.
OH MY GOODNESS!
OH MY GOSH,
THIS LOOKS AMAZING!
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR NEW MAINE STAYS!
15ENTREES UNDER $15,
SEAFOOD, CHICKEN AND MORE!
OOTHE TILAPIAWITH ROASTEDEGETAB!
I'M ACTUALLY LOOKING AT
THE WO GRILLED CHICKEN
WITH PORTOBELLO WINE SAUCE.
AT PORK CHOP
WAS GREAT!
NO MORE
FAST FOOD FRIDAY'S!
WE'RE GOING TO GO
TO RED LOBSTER.
YEP.
[ Male Announcer ]
COME TRY OUR NEW MENU
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
SALAD, SANDWICHES, AND MORE.
YOU WON'T TAKE OUR FUTURE.
AIDS AFFECTS US ALL.
EVEN BABIES.
CHEVRON IS WORKING TO STOP
MOTHER-TO-CHILD TRANSMISSION.
OUR EMPLOYEES AND THEIR FAMILIES
ARE PART OF THE FIGHT.
AND WE'RE WINNING.
AT CHEVRON NIGERIA, WE HAVEN'T
HAD A REPORTED CASE IN 12EARS.
AIDS IS STRONG.
BUT WE ARE STRONGER.
AND AIDS...
♪
AIDS IS GOING TO LOSE.
>>> WE HAVE ENDURED TOO MANY
OF THESE TRAG DEC IN THE PAST
FEW YEARS AND EACH TIME I
LEARN THE NEWS, I REACT NOT AS
A PRESIDENT BUAS ANYBODY ELSE
WOULD, AS A PARENT.
AND THAT WAS ESPECIALLY TRUE
TODAY.
I KNOW THERE IS NOT A PARENT
IN AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL
THE SAME OVERWHELPING GRIEF
THEY DO.
THE MAJOR OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5-10 YEARS OLD .
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
ATHEM.
BIRTH DAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS, MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES TO HELPING
OUR CHILDREN FULFILL THEIR
DREAMS AND SO OUR HEARTS ARE
BROKEN TODAY.
MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF
THE VICTIMS AND IN THE WORDS
OF SPRITZER.
HEAL THE BROKENHEARTED AND
BIND UP THEIR WOUNDS.
>>> THAT WAS PRESIDENT OBAMA
EARLIER EMOTIONS RUNNING HIGH
AS THE COUNTRY COPES WITH THE
SENSELESS TRAG 20 CHILDREN AND
6 ADULTS AND BREAKING MOMENTS
AGO, A SOURCE TOLD THE AP MORE
THAN TWO GUNS WERE FOUND IN
THE SCHOOL.
IT WAS RECENTLY REPORTED THAT
TWO HANDGUNS WERE FOUND.
FEDERAL AUTHORITIES ARE
WORKING TO TRACE THOSE FIRE
ARMS.
JOINING ME TO HELP EXPLAIN
WHAT THE POLICE DO NOW AND
WHERE THEY GO IN THE
INVESTIGATION .
ROD WHEELER WAS TEACHING A
COURSE ON ACTIVE SHOOTERS.
AND FORMER NYPD DETECTIVE JOE
COFFEY.
HE SUPERVISED THE LATE SON OF
SAM INVESTIGATION IN THE
1970S.
OBVIOUSLY THIS KID HAS
EMOTIONAL PROBLEMS AND YOU
HAVE TO BE CRAZY AND/OR EVIL
TO KILL -- THESE ARE BABIES.
KINDERGARTENERS HERE.
YOU DEALT WITH THIS.
>>> THIS GUY IS A SOC PATH
LIKE ALMOST ALL OF THEM ARE.
PEOPLE SAY THEY ARE MENTALLY
ILL AND THEY PROBABLY ARE.
PEOPLE LIKE HIM, THEY ARE
SOCIO PATHS.
>>> MEANING THEY DON'T CENTER
A CONSCIENCE AND A SENSE OF
RIGHT AND WRONG AND NO GUILT
ASSOCIATED WITH BERKOWITZ.
SON OF SAM.
ED HIM MOTIVE.
MY MOTHER PUT MEAVE UP FOR
ADOPTION.
IT IS CRAZY.
>>> IT IS IT FALLING BACK ON
AN EXCUSE.
THEY ARE SOCIO PATHS.
>>> THEY ARE OFFERING
COUNSELING TO FIRST RESPONDERS
BECAUSE THE SCENE WAS SO
HORRIFIC AND THE FAMILIES, I
DON'T KNOW HOW AS A PARENT AND
I AM A PARENT OF TWO KIDS DO
YOU EVER OVERCOME I DON'T KNOW
HOW THE RECOVERY COMING IN.
BUWHAT ARE POLICE DOING.
THEY HAVE TO GO THROUGH THE
HORROR OF IDENTIFYING THE
BODIES AND GOING AND TELLING
THE PARENTS, WHERE DO THEY GO
FROM HERE?
>>> THEY HAVE TO RESPOND TO A
CALL THAT INVOLVES CHILDREN.
IT IS ONE OF THE WORST THAT A
POLICE OFFICER CAN GO TOMPT
WHEN YOU SEE THE CARNAGE THAT
THE OFFICERS SAW TODAY.
IT IS UNBELIEVABLE AND THEY
WILL HAVE CONFLICT AS A MATTER
OF FACT.
WHAT THE POLICE ARE DOING
RIGHT NOW, THERE IS A NUMBER
OF THINGS.
A NUMBER OF UNANSWERED
QUESTIONS THAT WE ARE TRYING
TO FIGURE OUT.
WHAT WAS THE MOTIVE BEHIND THE
GUYS ACTION.
GRANTED HE WAS A SOCIO PATH.
BUTHERE IS IT ALWAYS A SPARK
AND WARNING SIGNS IN EVERYONE
OF THESE CASES.
RIGHT NOW THE INVESTIGATORS
AND ATF.
THEY ARE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHERE THESE GUYS GOT THE
AMMUNITION FROM AND WEAPONS
FROM WHY DID HE SELECT THIS
SCHOOL AND CLASSROOM?
WE ARE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
ALL OF THAT NOW.
>>> YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE AN
INVESTIGATOR TO PEACE TOGETHER
THE FACT HIS MOTHER WORKED
THERE AND HE KILLED HIS MOTHER
AND WENT TO THE SCHOOL.
HE SUFFERED FROM PERSONALITY
DISORDER OR PERHAPS TUST --
AUTISTIC OR MEDICATION MAYBE.
WE'LL CHECK IN WITH MEDICAL
EXPERTS LATER.
>>> IN MY BUSINESS AND LAW
ENFORCEMENT AREA.
YOU CONFRONT EVIL.
HE WAS THE EPITOME OF EVIL AS
TIMOTHY MACVEIGH AND
BERKOWITZ.
THEY ARE CREATURES THAT
SHOULDN'T WALK THE EARTH.
AND THESE TYPE OF PEOPLE, THEY
ARE IMMUNE TO RIGHT AND WRONG.
THEY HAVE NO CLUE.
>>> ONE LAST QUESTION.
WHEN A COP WALKS IN AND SEES
THAT, COPS SEE A LOT IN THE
COURSE OF THEIR CAREER.
>>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>>> THIS HAS GOT TO BE
PARTICULARLY TRAUMATIC EVEN
FOR THEM.
THEY HAVE TO GO IN THERE AND
IDENTIFY AND PEOPLE HAVE TO
CLEAN THIS UP.
IT IS TO BE DIFFICULT FOR
EVERYBODY INVOLVED IN EVERY
LEVEL.
>>> IT IS IT THE WORST
SCENARIO THAT WE CAN FIND
OURSELVES N. ALL POLICE
OFFICERS ARE PROFESSIONALS AND
WE ARE TRAIN TOD RESPOND AND
WE HAVE TO RESPOND IN THESE
SITUATIONS.
BUWHEN IT INVOLVES CHILDREN IT
IS THE WORST THING YOU CAN
EVER EXPERIENCE.
WE STILL HAVE TO GO IN AND
REMEMBER THEM.
WHEN THE FIRST OFFICER GOT ON
THE SCENE, THEY HAD NO
ICALLYCLUE WHETHER THER HAD
KILLED HIMSELF.
THEY HAVE TO ATTEND TO THE
INJURED BUHAD AN ACTIVE
SHOOTER TO TAKE OUT.
IT IS A TERRIBLE SITUATION TO
DEAL WITH, SEAN.
>>> I KNOW ONE THING, THESE
POLICE OFFICERS, THEY WILL
LIVE WITH THIS FOR THE REST OF
THEIR LIVES.
>>> NO DOUBT.
I DON'T KNOW HOW THE PARENTS
RECOVER.
AS A PARENT I DON'T KNOW HOW
YOU RECOVER.
>>> COMING UP.
YOU ARE LOOKING AT HOBOKEN,
NEW JERSEY THE HOME. BROTHER
RYAN LANZA AND PLUS WORD IS
BREAKING ABOUT THE SHOOTER'S
MENTAL CONDITION.
WE HAVE THE DETAILS AND STAY
WITH US.
FOR THE CONTINUING DEVELOP AMS
AS THEY COME IN THE FOX NEWS
CHANNEL.
Please Sir,
I want some more.
More?
He has asked for...
What?
Well he did say please...
Please and thank you.
Pass it on.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THEY ARE A GLOWING EXAMPLE
OF WHAT IT MEANS TO BE
THE BEST.
AND AT THIS SPECIAL TIME
OF YEAR,
THEY SHINE EVEN BRIGHTER.
COME TO THE WINTER EVENT
AND GET THE MERCEDES-BENZ
YOU'VE ALWAYS WISHED FOR,
NOW FOR AN EXCEPTIONAL PRICE.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
GLK350 FOR $399 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
GIVES YOU 1% CASH BACK
ON ALL PURCHASES,
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS.
AND EVERYONE...BUT HER
LIKES 50% MORE CASH.
BUT I'M UPPING MY GAME.
DO YOU WANT A CANDY CANE?
YES!
DO YOU WANT THE PUPPY?
DO YOU WANT A TRICYCLE?
YES!
DO YOU WANT
50 PERCENT MORE CASH?
NO!
♪
FESTIVE.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE Capital One
Cash Rewards Card
GIVES YOU
1% CASH BACK
ON EVERY
PURCHASE
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS
ON THE CASH YOU EARN.
IT'S THE CARD FOR PEOPLE
WHO LIKE MORE CASH.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
18 CHILDREN PRONOUNCED DEAD AT
THE SCHOOL AND TWO PRONOUNCED
DEAD AT THE HOSPITALS AND SIX
ADULTS PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE
SCHOOL.
THE SHOOTER IS DECEASED IN THE
>>> POLICE TRY TO PEACE
TOGETHER WHAT MADE 20 YEAR OLD
ADAM LANZA OPEN FIRE IN A
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL TODAY HIS
24 YEAR OLD BROTHER RYAN IS IN
POLICE CUSTODY BEING
QUESTIONED AT THIS HOUR.
THEY ARE OUTSIDE OF THE
APARTMENT IN HOBOKEN, NEW
JERSEY.
WHAT IS THE LATEST THAT YOU
ARE HEARING?
>>> JUST DURING THE COMMERCIAL
BREAK THEY WRAPPED UP THE
POLICE TAPE AND IT IS
GENERALLY A QUIET SCENE BEHIND
ME AND A VERY DIFFERENT SCENE
HERE AND PART OF THAT
CONFUSION LIKELY STEMMED FROM
THE FACT THAT RYAN LANZA ID
WAS FOUND ON ADAM LANZA.
YOU MENTIONED THAT HE IS
SPEAKING WITH POLICE.
THAT IS THE CASE.
HE IS NOT CONSIDERED A SUSPECT
NEITHER HE OR HIS GIRL FRIEND.
THEY ROLLE HERE EARLIER
THIS AFTERNOON AND A
RELIRADIABLE SOURCE SAID THEY
SAW POLICE SURROUNDING THE
BUILDING AND RYAN WAS HAND
CUFF TAKEN AWAY.
HE WAS DETERMINED NOT TO BE A
SUSPECT HOWEVER.
THERE WERE ALL THE SORTS OF
CONFLICTING REPORTS.
THEY THOUGHT SOMEONE WAS
MURDERED INSIDE OF THE
APARTMENT BUILDING BEHIND ME
OR THE FATHER.
THE FATHER IS COOPERATING WITH
THE FBI AND THEY ARE REALLY
TALKING TO THE FAMILY MEMBERS,
WE ARE LEARNING THAT ADAM
LANZA LIKELY HAD SOME FORM OF
AUTISM AND A PERMANENT
DISORDER.
BACK TO YOU.
>>> IS IT TRUE THAT RYAN HAD
NOT SPOKEN WITH ADAM IN TWO
YEARS,?
>>> WELL, SEAN I CAN TELL YOU
WE HEARD THE REPORTS, BUWE
HAVE NOT BEEN ABLE TO CONFIRM.
>>> THARCHING YOU.
AND IN THE AFTER MATH OF
TODAY'S TRAGEDY THERE WERE
REPORTS EARLIER THIS YEAR THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IMPLEMENTED SAFETY PROCEDURES
AND SO WHAT HAPPENED AND WHAT
ELSE CAN SCHOOLS DO TO PREVENT
INCIDENTS FROM HAPPENING IN
THE FUTURE?
JOINING ME IS DIRECTOR OF SAFE
HAVENS INTERNATIONAL.
I WAS PEEKING TO FRIENDS OF
MINE THAT ARE IN THE
EDUCATIONAL WORLD AND THEY ARE
VERY CLEAR, THIS SCHOOL WENT
ABOVE AND BEYOND TO GET BOO
SCHOOL, YOU HAD TO BE
IDENTIFIED, AND THEN BUZZED
IN.
AND IT SEEMS LIKE IN THIS
CASE.
THEY WERE DOING EVERYTHING
RIGHT, WHAT WOULD BE THE NEXT
STEP?
>>> SURE, THANKS FOR HAVING ME
ON.
AND WANT EXPRESS CONDOLENCES
TO THE COMMUNITY AND FAMILY.
I AM HEARING A NUMBER OF
INDICATIONS OF GOOD THINGS
THAT WERE IN PLACE IN THE
SCHOOL.
BUSECURITY IS ONLY STRONG AS
YOUR WEAKEST LINK.
YOU BUZZ THEM AND SCREEN THEM,
WE ARE COMMONLIED TO TEST
SECURITY AND CAN BREACH
SECURITY AND WE HAVE TO HAVE
GOOD TECHNOLOGY AND WE HAVE
EXCELLENT TECHNOLOGY TODAY AND
MAKE SURE WE ARE USING WHAT WE
KNOW ABOUT HOW PEOPLE CAN BE
TRAINED TO DETECT SUBTLE SIGNS
OF DANGER.
>>> DOES THAT MEAN.
>>> NO APPROACH IS FOOL PROOF.
>>> THAT'S THE POINT.
THE SON OF A TEACHER AT THE
SCHOOL WOULD BE SOMEBODY WHO
WOULD PROBABLY BE LET IN AND
YOU WOULDN'T KNOW AND THIS IS
IT A TOWN OF 27,000.
WELL-TO-DO COMMUNITY.
WALK IN AND GET FRISKED.
IS ANOTHER STEP THAT EVERY
COOL HAS ARMED GUARDS.
THEY CAN GET IN THERE FAIRLY
EARLY.
>>> THERE ARE OTHER TECH
TECHNIQUES THAT CAN BE USED .
WE HAVE HAD SHOOTINGS IN THE
SCHOOLS WITH METAL DETECTORS.
THERE ARE LIMITS TO THE
TECHNIQUES.
BUTHERE ARE THINGS IN TERMS OF
TRAINING OF STAFF AND PATTERN
MATCHING AND RECOGNITION AND
BASED AND STAFF IS TRAINED TO
PICK UP ON SUBTLE DIFFERENCES
WE SEE IT WHEN WE BUZZ IN THE
SCHOOLS TO TEST THEM.
I HAVE BEEN STOPPED BECAUSE
THEY DETECT SOMETHING IS NOT
RIGHT TO USE ABOUT THE STORE
TORE TO GET IN.
IF THE PERSON IS NORMALLY
COMING AND GOING FROM THE
SCHOOL IT WOULD BE UNREALISTIC
TO EXPECT THEY WOULD NOT BUZZ
THE SCHOOL INFORM WE'LL NOT
KNOW UNTIL THERE IS
INVESTIGATION .
A LOT OF SCHOOLS AND
ORGANIZATIONS PUT IN GOOD
TECHNOLOGY BUDON'T NECESSARILY
BACK TUP WITH GOOD TRAINING.
THE HUMAN BRAIN IS IT THE
GREATEST DEFENSE MECHANISM AND
STUR VIVAL MECHANISM KNOWN TO
MANKIND ACCORDING TO A
COLLEAGUE I RESPECT GREATLY.
HE'S RIGHT.
IF WE PROGRAM THE BRAIN AND
TEACH PEOPLE THERE ARE A
NUMBER OF INCIDENTS THAT HAVE
BEEN STOPPED THROUGH
TECHNIQUES.
BUNOTHING IS 100%.
>>> THANK YOU, SIR.
COMING UP NEXT.
WE ARE CONTINUING TO GET
DETAILS.
HIS BROTHER IS IN CUSTODY AND
PROVIDING CRUCIAL INFORMATION
ABOUT THE GUNMAN'S MENTAL
CONDITION.
WE'LL HAVE MORE ON THAT COMING
UP TODAY'S TRAGEDY REMINDS OF
COLUMBINE.
WE'LL SPEAK TO A FATHER WHO
LOST HIS DAUGHTER.
AND OFFERS THOUGHT TOTS
FAMILIES THAT LOST EVERYTHING
TODAY
THE SHOOTING APPEARS TO HAVE
STOPPED AND THE SCHOOL IS IN
LOCK DOWN.
I LOOK UP TO A LOT
OF THE OLDER HEADS, YOU KNOW,
THE INNOVATORS, THE HEADS
OF THE ART MOVEMENTS
OF THE PAST.
THEY KEPT IT REALLY EDGY,
AND, LIKE, A LOT
OF THE LATIN AMERICAN MURALISTS
AND THE LATIN AMERICAN ARTISTS,
THEIR STYLES ARE VERY UNIQUE
AND NEW TO THEIR TIME,
YOU KNOW,
SOMEWHAT CONTROVERSIAL,
BUT THAT'S
WHO I LOOK UP TO MAINLY.
PERSONALLY, I'M VERY EXCITED
ABOUT GOING TO COLLEGE.
IT'S SOMETHING NEW,
AND IT'S SOMETHING DIFFERENT
THAN WHAT I'M USED TO.
I'M DEFINITELY GOING TO BE
A LITTLE OUT OF MY ELEMENT,
BUT THAT'S WHAT MAKES IT SO
EXCITING IS THAT, YOU KNOW,
IT'S SOMETHING FRESH.
WELL, THERE'S SO MANY
OPPORTUNITIES THAT I THINK
I COULD MISS OUT ON
IF I DIDN'T GO, YOU KNOW.
GETTING INTO COLLEGE
TAKES PLANNING AND VISION.
YOU KNOW, IT'S JUST LIKE
WHEN I TAKE A BRICK WALL
AND TURN IT
INTO A CANVAS FOR MY ART.
PAINTING'S HELPED ME REALIZE
I'VE GOT WHAT IT TAKES.
ADT CAN HELP YOU
TURN ON A FEW LIGHTS.
ACCESS CAMERAS FROM ANYWHERE
TO HELP YOU KEEP AN EYE
ON THINGS.
EVEN BRING FAMILY IN
FROM THE COLD
WHEN YOU'RE NOT THERE.
NOW GET THE ADVANCED TECHNOLOGY
OF ADT
STARTING AT JUST $99
AND SAVE $300.
WITH ADT, YOU GET 24/7
FAST RESPONSE MONITORING
THAT HELPS PROTECT YOU
FROM BURGLARY, FIRE,
AND HIGH LEVELS
OF CARBON MONOXIDE.
PLUS REMOTE ACCESS
TO YOUR HOME.
EVEN CONTROL YOUR THERMOSTAT
TO HELP SAVE ENERGY AND MONEY.
GET ADT INSTALLED
STARTING AT JUST $99.
THAT'S A $300 SAVINGS.
YOU MAY EVEN SAVE UP TO 20%
ON YOUR HOMEOWNERS INSURANCE.
FOR EVERYTHING
THAT MATTERS MOST.
ADT. ALWAYS THERE.
>>> WE HEARD GUN SHOTS AND THE
GYM TEACHER DIRECTED US TO
STAY AGAINST THE WALL AND
EVERYONE STARTED PANICKING AND
THEN POLICEMEN CAME IN AND
THEY JUST LIKED IF HE WAS IN
HERE?
BUT THEN WE HAD TO CLIMB IN
THE CLOSEST.
WE HEARD MORE GUN SHOTS AND
THE AMBULANCE CAME AND THEN
THE POLICEMEN TOLD US TO RUN
OUT OF THE BUILD GO TO THE
FIRE DEPARTMENT.
>>> ONE LITTLE GIRL'S
FRIGHTENING ACCOUNT OF WHAT
HAPPENED IN SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AND THE COUNTRY MOURNS THE
TRAGEDY.
IT IS NOT THE FIRST SCHOOL
SHOOTING THAT THE NATION HAS
HAD TO DEAL WITH.
RACHEL WAS KILLED IN THE
COLUMBINE HIGH SCHOOL MASS
CURE.
DARRYL, AS A PARENT, ALL I CAN
THINK OF TODAY IS THESE
PARENTS OUT BUYING CHRISTMAS
GIFTS.
KIDS AT THIS AGE EXCITED ABOUT
SANTA CLAUS AND CHRISTMAS IS
IT COMING, AND NOW PLANNING A
FUNERAL AND NO CHRISTMAS OR
BIRTHDAYS, HOW DO YOU RECOVER?
YOU HAVE BEEN THROUGH THIS.
>>> WELL, THERE IS NOTHING YOU
CAN TELL A PARENT THAT LOST
THE CHILD.
THEY NEED THEIR FRIENDS AND
FAMILY.
IN OUR CASE, WE MADE CHOICES.
WE MADE THE CHOICE NOT TO BE
ANGRY AND BETTER BUT TO
CELEBRATE RACHEL'S LIFE AND
TODAY WE HAVE THE LARGEST
SCHOOL TRAINING PROGRAMS AND
REACH THREE MILLION STUDENTS A
YEAR WITH RACHEL'S CHALLENGE
AND TRAIN OVER 300,000
CHILDREN AND SCHOOL 500
SUICIDES PREVENTED.
A LOT OF THE ANSWERS ARE LONG
TERM.
THEY ARE NOT JUST A KNEE JERK
REACTION OR MORE LAWS AND
REGULATIONS .
BUT WE HAVE TO BE A KINDER
NATION AND TAKE TIME TO LISTEN
TO ONE ANOTHER AND BE ROLE
MODELS IN THESE KIDS.
AND YOU ARE ACTIVE AND IN YOUR
HEALING, AM I INTERPERTING IT
RIGHT.
MY SON CRAIG WAS IN THE
LIBRARY AND HE CAME WITHIN A
SPLIT SECOND OF BEING KILLED.
AND I WOULD HAVE LOST TWO
CHILDREN.
MY HEART GOES OUT TO THE
PARENTS WHO LOST THE CHILDREN
AND DEALING WITH THE TRAUMA OF
THE CHILDREN GOING THROUGH.
AND COUNSELING AND A THEY NEED
A LOT OF LOVE AND ATTENTION.
OUR HEARTS AND PRAYERS GO OUT
TO ALL OF THESE WONDERFUL POEM
THAT LOST CHILDREN TONIGHT.
>>> WHEN DUTHINK YOU STARTED
TO RECOVER.
IT TAKES A LONG TIME TO HEAL
THIS PAIN.
HOW LONG DID IT TAKE YOU TO
TURN THE CORNER A LITTLE BIT.
>>> HONESTLY, YOU NEVER
TOTALLY HEAL.
THERE IS ALWAYS A HOLE IN YOUR
HEART WHEN YOU LOSE A CHILD.
WE HAVE CHILDREN AND GRAND
CHILDREN.
BUT THERE IS ALWAYS A MISSING
GAP THERE WITH RACHEL.
IT DOES -- YOU GO THROUGH
STAGES OF SHOCK ASK DISBELIEF
AND ANGER AND WHOLE GAMUT OF
EMOTIONS AND THE INITIAL STING
IN THE FIRST TWO OR THREE
YEARS BEGINS TO WEAR OFF AND
YOU NEVER LOSE IT COMPLETEY
LOO.
AND CELEBRATING THEIR LIVES
AND FOCUS ON THAT AND NOT
DIRECT THE ANGER TOWARD THE
SHOOTER AND EVEN FRACTIS AND
THIS IS NOT A TIME FOR THOSE
PARENT TO HEAR BUT WE CHOSE TO
FORGIVE AND SOME PEOPLE CAN'T
DO THAT.
FORGIVENESS AND FOCUSING ON
THE POSITIVE IN YOUR CHILD'S
LIFE GOES A LONG WAY TO
HELPING.
DARRYL, SORRY ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED TO YOUR DAUGHTER AND
THANKS FOR SHARING YOUR
EXPERIENCE AND HELPING MORE
PEOPLE.
NAND THE SHOTTER MAY HAVE
SUFFERED FROM A PERSONALITY
DISORDER.
JOINING ME NOW ABOUT THE
SHOOTER'S MENTAL CONDITION.
WE HAVE DOCTORS HERE PART OF
THE FOX MEDICAL TEEM.
WE HEARD PERSONALITY DISORDER.
I HEARD THE TERM AUTISM AND
ASBERGER'S SYNDROME.
OBVIOUS LOW THE KID AT THIS
AGE SHOOTING HIS MOTHER AND
GOING INTO SHOOT WITH ABANDON
ALL OF THESE KIDS.
WOULD ANY OF THOSE CONDITIONS
TELL YOU THAT CAN HAPPEN?
>>> HE IS OUT OF TOUCH WITH
REALITY.
IF HE HAD ASBERGER'S HE MAY
HAVE HAD ONGOING MELT DOWNS
ASSOCIATED WITH VIOLENT
BEHAVIOR.
IT IS POSSIBLE HE WAS ON
MEDICATION AND IT WAS NOT
WORKING AND HE DIDN'T HAVE
EMPATHY AND HAD SOCIAL
PROBLEMS.
BUT THAT DOESN'T EXPLAIN
EVERYTHING AND GIVEN THE AGE
OF 20, THAT HE BECAME PSCOTIC
AND HE HAD A DELUSIONAL SYSTEM
THAT LED TO A HEINOUS CRIME.
>>> IS IT ALWAYS A MEDICAL
CONDITION.
IF SOMEONE IS DISCONNECTED
FROM ROLIT AND NO SIM THEE OR
CONSCIOUSNESS AND NO SOUL,
THERE IS HUMAN EVIL, I MEAN
SOMEBODY CAN KILL INNOCENT
CHILDREN LIKE IT SEEMS TO ME
THAT IS IT EVIL.
>>> I DON'T KNOW WHAT THE
DOCTOR'S OPINION IS ON I DON'T
LET POEM OFF OF THE HOOK AND
SAY IT IS IT A MENAL
CONDITION.
IT IS AN ISSUE OF EVIL HERE AS
WELL.
>>> HERE'S WHAT I THINK >>>
THE COMMON DENOMINATOR.
LACK OF EMPATHY.
YOU CAN'T WALK UP TO THE CHILD
AND KILL IT AND SIGH THE CHILD
FALL TO THE GROUND OR SLUMP
OVER AND MAINTAINING ANY
EMPATHY.
WHY CAN YOU LOSE HUMAN
YOU CAN BE DELUSIONAL AND
WORKING ON A DELUSIONAL
SYSTEM.
BUT YOU COULD BE IF YOU THINK
I DO THIS I SAVE THE WHOLE
WORLD.
AND THAT IS ONE LEVEL.
AND SURE PERSONALITY DISORDERS
CAN DO THIS AND OTHER
CONDITIONS LIKE DRUG ABUSE
COMBINED WITH EITHER A MOOD
DISORDER OR PERSONALITY OR ALL
THREE.
BUT IS IT A MENTAL ILLNESS.
OF COURSE IT IS.
THAT LACK OF EMPATHY DOESN'T
COME FROM NO WHERE.
AND IN 20 YEARS SEAN I NEVER
FOUND ANYBODY WHO DOES
ANYTHING LIKE THIS THAT BEEN
THROUGH HELL IN A WAY THAT
CREATES MENTAL ILLNESS.
>>> THIS IS IMPORTANT I THINK.
FIRST RESPHONDERS ARE GOING TO
NEED COUNSELING AND THE
PARENTS.
AS A PARENT THEY ARE GOING TO
NEED COUNSELING.
AND STUNES ARE GOING TO BE
TRAUMATIZED AND POST TRAUMATIC
STRESS AND DIFFERENT AND ALL
LIKE WANT TROOPS GO THROUGH.
WHAT DO YOU EXPECT TO HAPPEN
TO THE PEOPLE IN >>> THE VET
ADMINISTRATION LOCKED AT 600
KIDS WHO WERE, THANK GOD
WEREN'T KILLED WILL HAVE
STRESS DISORDER AND THEY WILL
BE AGGRESSIVE, SAD OR NOT
FEELING HELP AND NOT SLEEPING
WELL.
IT CAN LAST FOR MONTHS AND
MONTHS IF NOT YEARS.
COGNITIVE THERAPY HELPS.
THANK YOU.
AND COMING UP NEXT.
A FORMER RESIDENT OF THAT
TIGHT KNIT COMMUNITY IS
STANDING BY.
THAT IS COMING UP NEXT RIGHT
HERE ON HANNITY.
Music is a universal language.
But when I was in an accident...
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
Information on my phone.
Connection to doctors who
get where I'm from.
And tools to estimate what
my care may cost.
So I never missed a beat.
We're more than 78,000
people looking out for
more than 70
million Americans.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.
THEY DON'T HELP SINGLE MOMS.
HI!
[ Sarah ] WHAT HAPPENED
TO OUR HOUSE LAST YEAR?
[ Daughters ] IT FLOODED
AND THE WATER FLOODED OUT. YEAH.
[ Sarah ] THE RED CROSS
ARRANGED THE HOTEL FOR US.
THEY GAVE ME THAT BREAK,
THAT LEVERAGE,
TO BE ABLE TO GET IT TOGETHER
AND TAKE CARE OF THEM. YOU KNOW?
I FEEL LIKE WE'VE COME
FULL CIRCLE.
[ Daughter 1 ] LIKE THAT!
[ Daughter 2 ]
THIS IS HOW I'LL DO IT.
[ Sarah ] THERE YOU GO.
I HAD[ Designer ]EELING
ENOUGH OF JUST COVERING UPDO IT.
MY MODERATE TO SEVERE
PLAQUE PSORIASIS.
I DECIDED ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
♪
[ Spa Lady ]
I STARTED ENBREL.
IT'S CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO PROVIDE CLEARER SKIN.
[ RV Guy ] ENBREL MAY NOT WORK
FOR EVERYONE --
AND MAY NOT CLEAR YOU
COMPLETELY,
BUT FOR MANY, IT GETS SKIN
CLEARER FAST, WITHIN 2 MONTHS,
AND KEEPS IT CLEARER
UP TO 9 MONTHS.
[ Male Announcer ]
BECAUSE ENBREL®, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL,
EVENTS INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS, LYMPHOMA,
OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING ENBREL,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START ENBREL IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON ENBREL, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING,
OR PALENESS.
IF YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH, ASK
YOUR DERMATOLOGIST ABOUT ENBREL.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO HANUTY AS
WE CONTINUED THE REPORT ON THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
WE GO BACK TO CONNECTICUT
WHERE A RESIDENT OF THAT TIGHT
KNIT COMMUNITY IS JOINING US.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US.
>>> YOU'RE WELCOME, SEAN.
>>> TELL US ABOUT THE PRAYER
VIGIL AND INFORMATION YOU
MIGHT HAVE PICKED UP TODAY.
>>> THE PRAYER VIGIL WAS
ABSOLUTE LOW BEAUTIFUL.
IT WAS JUST UNBELIEVABLE HOW
MANY PEOPLE SHOWED UP AT THIS
CHURCH AND PEOPLE OUTSIDE AND
JUST CRYING.
AND LOVE AND HUGGING EACH
OTHER.
IT WAS ABSOLUTELY WONDERFUL.
>>> YEAH.
>>> I AM STOW GLAD I ATTENDED
IT.
>>> I AM GLAD YOU DID AS WELL.
I KNOW THE COMMUNITY WILL NODE
A LOT OF HEALING.
IT IS IT A VERY SMALL
TIGHT-KNIT TOWN.
27,000 PEOPLE AND KNOWN AS A
SAFE NEIGHBORHOOD, CORRECT?
>>> ABSOLUTELY.
THERE IS NO CRIME IN NEWTOWN.
THIS IS IT JUST AN ISOLATED
INCIDENT AND HE WAS NOT EVEN A
RESIDENT HERE.
HE WAS FROM NEW JERSEY AND HE
USED TO LIVE THERE.
>>> HIS MOTHER LIVED NEARBY
AND SHE WAS KILLED BEFORE HE
WENT ON THE SCHOOL RAMPAGE.
>>> UNBELIEVABLE.
IT IS VERY, VERY SAD.
>>> WERE THERE PARENTS AND
SOME OF THE KIDS FROM THE
SCHOOL AT THE VIGIL, MA'AM?
NYES, YES, CRYING.
JUST HUGGING THEIR PARENTS AND
CRYING.
AND I WAS HUGGING MY GRAND
DAUGHTER AND MY DAUGHTER, IT
WAS JUST THARCHINGFUL THAT WE
ARE ALIVE.
>>> THANK YOU, FOR SHARE THAG
WITH US.
WHEN WE COME BACK OUR GOOD
FRIEND BO DEDLE IS WITH US.
AND YOU WILL HEAR WHAT ONE
FIRST GRADE TEACHER TOLD HER
STUDENTS WHEN THEY WERE
WAITING FOR THE POLICE TO
ARRIVE.
THAT EMOTIONAL STORY IS COMING
UP NEXT.
(SIREN)
SNOTE
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
BORN FROM THE ELEMENTS.
♪
DESTINED TO TAKE THEM OVER.
THE UCONNECT COMMAND CENTER
WITH SIRIUS XM SATELLITE RADIO
IN THE NEW 2013 RAM 1500.
ENGINEERED TO MOVE HEAVEN
AND EARTH.
GUTS. GLORY.
RAM.
>> I AM THINKING AS A SIX OR
SEN YEAR OLD WHAT ARE YOUR
THOUGHTS?
I AM THINKING I HAVE TO BE
THEIR PARENT AND HAVE TO TELL
THEM AND I SAID I NEED YOU TO
KNOW THEY LOVE YOU ALL VERY
MUCH.
AND THAT IT IS GOING TO BE
OKAY.
I THOUGHT THAT WAS THE LAST
THING WE WERE GOING TO HEAR
AND I THOUGHT WE WERE ALL
GOING TO DIE .
I DON'T KNOW IF THAT IS OKAY,
TEACHERS, BUT I WANTED THEM TO
KNOW I LOVED THEM AND THAT
WOULD BE ONE OF THE LAST
THINGS THEY HEARD AND NOT THE
GUN FIRE IN THE HALLWAY.
IT IS HORRIBLE, HORRIBLE.
>> THAT WAS A FIRST GRADE
TEACHER IN SANY HOOK
ELEMENTARY THINKING ABOUT HER
UNBELIEVABLE DAY AND LIKELY TO
HEAR MORE STORIES AS THE
TRAGEDY UNFOLDS .
HERE IS DR. MICHAEL BODEN.
FORMER NYPD DETECTIVE BO.
AND PSYCHE THERAPIST IS HERE
WITH US.
TUNES AND TEACHERS AND BO HAS
SEWN A LOT IN HIS DAY.
THEY WILL BE DEALING WITH A
LOT.
>> IT IS EXTRAORDINARILY
TRAUMATIZING.
NTO THE PARTNERS THE MOST?
>> RIGHT.
GETTING HEALING IS MOST
IMPORTANT.
WHAT PARENTS CAN DO FOR THE
CHILDREN.
GET THEM HOME SO THEY ARE IN A
COMFORTABLE SITUATION AND
PROVIDE THEM WITH STRUCTURE.
STRUCTURE IS VERY COMFORTING
AND NOT OVERWHELM THEM WITH
TOO MUCH INFORMATION BUT BE A
PERSON .
>> WOULD YOU HAVE THEM GO TO
VIGILS AND FUNERALS OR DEPENDS
ON THE KID.
>> IT DEPENDS ON THE KID AND
THE SITUATION.
IF THEIR CHILD LOST A GOOD
FRIEND IT MIGHT BE GOOD TO
TAKE THEM TO THE FUNERAL.
IT WOULD BE OKAY.
AND THEY DON'T GET FRIGHTENED
AND IT IS OKAY TO HAVE A
BROADRANGE OF E.
- EMOTION .
>> I HAVE SIX CHILDREN AND
1984, WE HAD THE PALM SUNDAY
MASSCURE.
THIS MAN WENT IN A HOUSE AND
SHOT AND KILLED 10 KIDS.
THEY WERE ALL SITTING AROUND
AND NO ONE RAN AWAY.
IT IS IT A FREEZE THING.
WHEN SOMEONE IS SYSTEMATICALLY
SHOOTING PEOPLE KIDS FREEZE.
IT IS LIKE THEY WERE ALL 12
AND UNDER.
SIX YORE OLD AND FIVE YORE OLD
AND THESE KIDS WERE ALL
SITTING AROUND AND ALL HAD
SHOTS.
>> YOU SAW TEMPERATURE >>
VIVID IN MY MIND AND THE FIRST
RESPONDERS I AM SURE THAT WAS
HORRIFIC.
10 DAY I SAW AND LARGEST MASS
MURDER IN NEW YORK HISTORY
BEFORE 9/11.
THAT IS BURNED IN MY BRAIN.
I CAN JUST IMAGINE WHAT THIS
WAS.
HOW COME THERE WAS NO
SURVIVORS.
THIS PUNK.
PROBABLY SHOT THEM IN THE HEAD
AND IF HE SHOT BODY SHOTS, WE
WOULD HAVE HAD A LOT MORE
SURVIVORS.
>> DOCTOR, YOU HAVE SEEN MANY.
NI DID THE AUTOPSIES ON THOSE.
>> YOU HAVE SEEN A LOT.
HOW DO YOU KIND OF, I GUESS IT
IS LIKE ANY JOB, YOU HAVE TO
FIND A WAY TO COMPARTMENTALIZE
WHAT YOU ARE WITNESSING OR YOU
DON'T SURVIVE.
>> IN A SENSE, THE DECEEDENTS
ARE OUT OF THE PAIN AND
MISERY.
IT IS IT THE PARTNERS AND
FAMILIES.
THEY ARE GOING THROUGH A STATE
THAT WILL LAST A FEW DAYS
UNTIL THEY GET THEIR BABIES
BACK.
THE SIVENADULTS WILL BE
AUTOPSIED ESPECIALLY THE
PERPETRATOR.
BUT THE CHILDREN HAVE TO BE
EXAMINED AND THEY HAVE
DOCUMENT THE INJURIES ON THE
CHILDREN AND IF THERE ARE
BULLETS IN THE BODIES THEY
HAVE TO BE REMOVED.
TO MATCH IT UP TO THE WEAPONS
AND MAKE SURE THERE WAS NOT A
WEAPON THEY DON'T KNOW ABOUT.
IT TAKES TIME.
>> IT COMES BACK.
AND I HAVE BEEN INVOLVED WITH
THIS SAFE SCHOOL THING AND SEE
SOMETHING NOTIFY.
AND CALL NUMBER THERE.
AND IT IS COMING DOWN.
I GET CALLS IN THE OFFICE.
SCHOOLS NOW ARING FOR OFF DUTY
COPS WITH A GUN.
LET'S BE HONEST IF A GUY HAD A
GUN, HE MIGHT HAVE KILLED SOME
PEOPLE YOU WOULD AT LEAST BE
ABLE TO LIMIT IT.
>> THAT'S WHAT I WANT.
>> THAT'S WHY THEY TARGET
SCHOOL SYSTEMS.
>> IT IS GOING TO COME DOWN TO
IT.
THESE ARE PRECIOUS THINGINGS.
WE'LL PAY FOR A RETIRED COP
WITH A GUN SO ONE OF THESE
PUNKS COME IN.
HE WILL NOT HAVE FREE WILL.
IF HE HAD MORE BULLETS AND
TIME, HE COULD HAVE KILLED
MORE UNTIL THOSE COPS GOT
THERE.
IT IS HORRIFIC.
>> I THINK WE ARE HEADED THERE
ESPECIALLY COPS IN NEW YORK.
>> I THINK IT IS IT GREAT.
BUT THE GOOD NEWS, KIDS ARE
RESILIENT D