USING YOUR PHOTOS IN THEIR ADS
WITHOUT PAYING YOU.
THERE IS NO WAY TO OPT OUT.
THIS IS THEIR FIRST BIG POLICY
SHIFT SINCE FACEBOOK BOUGHT IT
OUT.
SOME EXPERTS SAY THIS COULD PUT
THE COMPANY OUT OF BUSINESS
SINCE MAYBE YOU DON'T WANT YOUR
PHOTO TO SHOW UP IN AN AD.
USERS ARE NOT HAPPY.
WE ARE GETTING LOTS OF TWEETS ON
THE LAST TWO SEGMENTS WE DID AND
WE ARE TAKING YOUR THOUGHTS ON
BOTH OF THEM.
ONE WRITES ABOUT KELLY'S COURT
THAT POLICE OFFICERS HAVE TO
FREQUENTLY GET OUT OF THEIR
VEHICLES FOR EMERGENCIES AND,
THEREFORE, CANNOT WEAR THEIR
SEATBELTS.
HMMMM MM...OKAY.
>>Shepard: STUDENTS IN NEWTOWN
RETURN TO CLASS FOR THE FIRST
TIME SINCE THE GUNMAN DEVASTATED
THE COMMUNITY AS FAMILIES HOLD
MORE FUNERALS.
A LIVE REPORT COMING FROM
NEWTOWN IN A MOMENT AND COPS IN
NORTHERN ILLINOIS ISSUING
WARRANTS FOR 20 FRAT BROTHERS
AFTER THEY SAY A PLEDGE TURNED
UP DEAD AFTER A BOOZE-FUELED
HAZING RITUAL.
AND A NEW WARNING ON GRAPEFRUIT
WITH A GROWING LIST OF
MEDICATIONS THAT WILL SCREW
EVERYTHING UP.
THAT IS ALL AHEAD UNLESS
BREAKING NEWS CHANGES
EVERYTHING.
ON "STUDIO B."
BUT, FIRST, FROM FOX AT 3:00 IN
NEW YORK CITY THE KIDS RUN TO
CLASS AT MOST SCHOOLS ACROSS
NEWTOWN, CUT, BUT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IS AN ACTIVE
CRIME SCENE AND COULD STAY
CLOSED FOR MONTHS.
THE TOWN IS COMING TO GRIPS WITH
THE SHOOTING MASSACRE.
SCHOOL BUSS ARE BACK IN THE
STREETS DECORATED WITH GREEN AND
WHITE RIBBONS, THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL COLORS.
TODAY, FAMILY AND FRIENDS
ATTENDED FUNERALS FOR TWO MORE
60 YEAR OLDS.
MANY MORE SERVICES ARE PLANNED
FOR THE DAYS AHEAD AS FAMILIES
GRIEVE THE LOSSES OF 20 KIDS AND
SIX ADULTS WHO DIED BEFORE THE
GUNMAN KILLED HIMSELF.
IT COULD TAKE LONGER FOR THE
TOWN TO RETURN TO A NORMAL WAY
OF LIFE.
FOLKS ARE DOING WHAT THEY CAN TO
HELP.
THIS 9-1-1 OPERATOR IN
CALIFORNIA ARRANGED TO BUY THE
MORNING COFFEE FOR FOLKS AROUND
NEWTOWN.
>> I WANTED TO DO MORE THAN
DONATE A FEW DOLLARS.
I CANNOT AFFORD TO BUY BREAKFAST
BUT I CAN BUY THEM A CUP OF
COFFEE.
>> HE POSTED THIS ONLINE OTHERS
CHIPPED IN WITH CHOCOLATE AND
OTHER SNACKS.
AS FOR THE KIDS AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL THE DISTRICT
WILL TAKE CLASSES AT AN UNUSED
SCHOOL BUILDING NEARBY.
AND NOW OUR COVERAGE FROM
NEWTOWN, AND BECAUSE OF A THREAT
ANOTHER SCHOOL DID NOT OPEN
TODAY.
Rick: UNFORTUNATELY, SINCE
FRIDAY'S SHOOTING AUTHORITIES
HAVE BEEN FORCED TO DEAL WITH A
NUMBER OF BOMB THREATS.
THEY HAVE NOT PANNED OUT BUT ALL
HAVE TO BE CHECKED OUT INCLUDING
ONE OF THE SCHOOLS IN NEWTOWN
TODAY.
SIX OF THE SEVEN SCHOOLS WERE
SCHEDULED TO RE-OPEN ON A TWO
HOUR DELAY WITH POLICE OFFICERS
AT ALL THE SCHOOLS.
THIS MORNING, BEFORE THE SCHOOL
WAS SET TO RE-OPEN THAT SCHOOL
DID NOT ALLOW THE KIDS IN BUT
BROUGHT IN A BOMB SQUAD.
AN UNFORTUNATE DEVELOP 349 FOR
THE STUDENT WHOSE HELPED TO GO
BACK TO CLASS AND RETURN TO
NORMALCY AT THAT ONE SCHOOL.
OTHER KIDS DID RETURN TO CLASS
IN NEWTOWN, FAMILY AND FRIENDS
GATHERED AT THE CHURCH FOR TO
FUNERALS THAT, SADLY,
OVERPLANNED, AS ONE CASKET WAS
BEING CARRIED  MOURNERS WERE
ARRIVING TO PAY LAST REPUBLICS
TO JENNIFER REKOS.
OF COURSE, THERE ARE SEVERAL
MORE FUNERALS LANDED TOMORROW
AND EVERY OTHER DAY THIS WEEK.
>>Shepard: WE LEARNED FROM
AUTHORITIES THE SHOOTER WAS NOT
ON MEDICATION AT THE TIME OF THE
SHOOTING.
Rick: THAT IS WHAT WE HEAR
FROM THE HARTFORD COURANT WHO
POUND NO EVIDENCE THAT HE WAS
TAKING ANY MEDICATION WHATEVER
FOR THE ASPERGERS, A FORM OF
AUTISM, AND NO EVIDENCE HE HAD
SOON ANY DOCTORS OR SEEING A
DOCTOR FOR THE CONDITION.
INVESTIGATORS ARE SERVING
WARRANTS TO OBTAIN MEDICAL
RECORDS TO DETERMINE IF HE WAS
DIAGNOSED.
IF SO, WITH WHAT.
WAS HE PRESCRIBED MEDICATION.
IF SO, WHAT DOSE.
AND WHAT ROLE THIS MIGHT HAVE
PLAYED IN THE SHOOTING.
SOURCES SAY THAT ADAM TRIED TO
COVER HIS ELECTRONIC FOOTPRINTS
BY SMASHING THE HARD DRIVE OF
THE COMPUTER HE USED IN ONE OF
THE BEDROOMS HE USED INSIDE HIS
FAMILY'S SPRAWLING HOME.
THAT SMASHED HARD DRIVE NOW
BEING COMBED BY INVESTIGATORS
WHO HELP TO RECOVER SOME SORT OF
EVIDENCE TO EXPLAIN THE
SHOOTING.
>>Shepard: THANK YOU, RISK.
DEMOCRATIC LAWMAKERS AND
MILLIONS OF OTHERS SAY THE
MASSACRE IN NEWTOWN IS PROOF
THAT OUR NATION NEEDS STRICTER
GUN CONTROL LAWS AND NEEDS IT
NOW.
THE CALIFORNIA SENATOR FEINSTEIN
IS DRAFTING NEW LEGISLATION TO
BRING BACK THE NATION-WIDE BAN
ON ASSAULT WEAPONS THAT EXPIRED
EIGHT YEARS AGO.
SENATOR FEINSTEIN CALLED
PRESIDENT OBAMA% NAME YESTERDAY
IN THE HOPES OF STARTING A
DISCUSSION ON GUNS AND, TODAY,
THE WHITE HOUSE SAID THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA DOES SUPPORT HER
EFFORTS.
IN RESPONSE SO FAR FROM MANY PRO
GUN GROUPS INCLUDING THE
NATIONAL RIFLE ASSOCIATION.
BUT FOX HAS LEARNED THAT CAN
CHANGE.
JAMES IS LIVE IN WASHINGTON, DC.
JAMES?
>> SOURCES CLOSE TO THE ISSUE
SAY THE NATIONAL RIFLE
ASSOCIATION THAT HAS BEEN SILENT
SINCE NEWTOWN FROM RESPECT OF
THE MOURNING WILL "PUSH BACK
AGAINST THE VOCAL GUN CONTROL
LOBBY."
INDUSTRY SOURCES SAY THE N.R.A.
WILL BROADEN THE DISCUSSION TO
INCLUDE HOLLYWOOD AND THE GAMING
INDUSTRY AND THE GROUP WILL
CHALLENGE THE EFFORT UNDERWAY TO
RESTORE THE BAN ON ASSAULT
WEAPONS THAT EXISTED FROM 1994
TO 2004.
GUN ADVOCATES POINT OUT THE
COLUMBINE MASSACRE CARRIED OUT
WITH ASSAULT WEAPONS, OCCURRED
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE BAN'S LIFE
SPAN.
>> IF YOU LOOK AT THE DATA HERE,
WE BAN THIS ONE TIME IN 1994.
IF YOU LOOK AT THE NATURAL
INSURANCE INSTITUTE OF JUSTICE
STUDY ON THE BAN, AND THE
UNIVERSITY STUDY FROM THE
UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA
BERKELEY, NOT PRO GUN RIGHT
THOUGHT, THERE WAS NO IMPACT ON
LOWERING HOMICIDE RIGHT AND NO
IMPACT ON LOWERING MASS MURDERS
AND NO IMPACT ON THE NUMBER OF
BULLET AS VICTIM WAS SHOT WITH.
>>Reporter: SENATOR FEINSTEIN,
A DEMOCRAT, SAYS THE FIRST DAY
OF THE NEXT CONGRESS, JANUARY 3,
SHE WILL INROW DUES AN UPDATED
VERSION OF THE BAN SHE AUTHORED
TWO DECADES AGO.
MORE THAN 100 KINDS OF FIREARMS
WILL BE OUTLAWED BUT LEGALLY
OWNED ONES WILL BE GRANDFATHERED
IN.
>> EVERYONE WALKS AROUND HERE,
TOO MANY, WORRIES OF THEIR
N.R.A. SCORE.
THEY SCORE SOTOMAYOR'S
NOMINATION.
THEY SCORED WHETHER THE ATTORNEY
GENERAL WAS HELD IN CONTEMPT.
I HAVE TWO WORDS FOR THE N.R.A.:
SCORE THIS.
>> SENATOR MANCHIN FROM WEST
VIRGINIA SAID AFTER TALKING WITH
PRESIDENT OBAMA ABOUT GUN
CONTROL TODAY THAT NO ONE SHOULD
BE "VILIFIED" FOR SPEAKING WITH
PEOPLE WITH WHOM YOU MAY NOT
AGREE.
>>Shepard: THANK YOU, JAMES.
GUN STORE OWNERS SAY THE
POTENTIAL FOR AN ASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN HAS LED MANY MENS TO BUY
MORE GUNS AFTER THE DEADLY
SHOOTING.
ONE STORE IN SAN DIEGO REPORTS
THAT LAST SATURDAY WAS THE
BUSIEST DAY FOR SALES IN 20
YEARS.
HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE LINED UP FOR
A WEEKEND GUN SHOW IN NATURE AND
LAST WEEKEND IN SOUTHEAST
WISCONSIN STORES REPORTEDLY SOLD
MORE OF THE AR-15 ASSAULT RIFLE
THAN ANY OTHER FIREARM.
THE GUNMAN IN NEW STAY TUNED.
TUESDAYED A MODEL OF THIS.
AND REPUBLICANS AND DEMOCRATS
COULD BE GETTING CLOSER TO A
POINT TO AVOID THE FISCAL CLIFF,
PARTICULARLY WHEN IT COMES TO
INCOME TAXES.
WITH JUST TWO WEEKS TO GO UNTIL
THE END OF THE YEAR DEADLINE
THERE IS NO SOLID COMPROMISE
ONS IS, MEDICARE AND OF COURSE
THE NATIONAL DEBT LIMIT.
ED HENRY IS LIKE AT THE WHITE
HOUSE MORE THIS AFTERNOON.
ED, SPEAKER BOEHNER IS OFFERING
A NEW PLAN TODAY.
WILL THIS JUMP START THE TALKS?
>>Reporter: SOME THOUGHT IT
MIGHT BUT IT HAS DONE THE
OPPOSITE, SLOWED THE TALKS DOWN.
SPEAKER BOEHNER SAYING, LOOK,
WHY NOT JUST TRY TO DO A SMALLER
BIT OF THIS AND BASICALLY JUST
SET A NEW THRESHHOLD OF $1
MILLION OR MORE FOR RAISING
TAXES, DEAL WITH THAT AS SORT OF
A SO-CALLED PLAN (B) BECAUSE HE
IS FRUSTRATED THAT THE BROADER
DIFFERENT DEAL DOESN'T SEEM TO
BE GOING ANYWHERE.
>> IT WOULD BE BETTER FOR OUR
COUNTRY BUT AT THIS POINT HAVING
A BACKUP PLAN TO MAKE SURE THAT
FEW AMERICAN TAXPAYERS WERE
AFFECTED BY THIS INCREASE AS
POSSIBLE, MOVING DOWN THAT PATH
IS THE RIGHT COURSE OF ACTION
FOR US.
>> THE PROBLEM IS, IT IS NOT
CLEAR THAT RANK AND FILE HOUSE
REPUBLICANS IN HIS OWN CAUCUS
SUPPORT JUST DOING THE SMALLER
MEASURE SO IT DOESN'T APPEAR TO
HAVE MOVED THE BALL FORWARD.
>>Shepard: IT DOESN'T SOUND
LIKE THE WHITE HOUSE IS ON WITH
THIS?
>> NO, CARNEY SAID IT IS DEAD ON
ARRIVAL AND THE BIG PROBLEM IN
THE WHITE HOUSE EYES IS THIS
WOULD NOT RAISE ENOUGH REVENUE
IF YOU SET THE THEY HOLD $1
MILLION OR MORE.
THE PRESIDENT HAS WANTED TO SET
THE THRESHHOLD OF $250,000 OR
MORE, AND JAKE CARNEY SAYS THE
PRESIDENT IS MOVING TOWARD THE
REPUBLICANS AND THEY ARE MEET
MEETING HALFWAY.
>> THE PRESIDENT HAS ALREADY
MOVED HALFWAY ON REVENUE.
MORE THAN HALFWAY ON SPENDING
CUTS.
THAT IS BY DEFINITION WHAT
COMPROMISE IS ABOUT, MEETING YOU
HALFWAY.
THE PRESIDENT IS HERE.
THE REPUBLICANS ARE HERE.
THE PRESIDENT HAS COME HALFWAY.
THE REPUBLICANS HAVE COME THIS
FAR.
SO WE ARE CLOSE.
>> THEY SAY THEY ARE CLOSE AND
THEY HAVE BEEN MAKING BABY STEPS
OF PROGRESS BEHIND-THE-SCENES
BUT IN PUBLIC WE ARE SEEING NO
SIGN THEY HAVE MOVED THAT MUCH
CLOSER TOGETHER TO AVOID THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
>>Shepard: THANK YOU, ED.
>> A REAL SIGH OF RELIEF ACROSS
AMERICA TODAY, AS THE VERY HIGH
PROFILE AMERICAN JOURNALIST FOR
NBC NEWS AND HIS CREW WERE FOUND
SAFE AFTER THEY HAD BEEN IN
CAPTIVITY FOR FIVE DAYS.
IT IS NOT TAXPAYER THEY WERE
RELEASED IN SYRIA, BUT THEY
ESCAPED AFTER A FIREFIGHT.
WE WILL HEAR FROM RICHARD ENGEL
ABOUT THE PSYCHOLOGICAL TORTURE
HE ENCURED AT THE HANDS OF THE
SYRIAN REGIME.
YOU TAKE THE PICTURE.
YOU ED IT THE PICTURE.
YOU POST THE PICTURE ONLINE AND
NOW FACEBOOK'S NEW ACQUISITION
WILL SELL THAT PICTURE WITHOUT
PAYING YOU OR EVEN TELLING YOU.
>> A KIDNAPPING, AND DAYS OF
PSYCHOLOGICAL TORTURE, A
FIREFIGHT BETWEEN FIREFIGHTS AND
PRO GOVERNMENT THUGS THAT IS
WHAT A VETERAN JOURNALISTS
SURVIVED IN WAR TORN SYRIA THE
MAN IN QUESTION IS THE NBC NEWS
CHIEF FOREIGN AFFAIRS
CORRESPONDENT, RICHARD ENGEL WHO
ONCE WORKED HERE.
HE AND HIS TEAM WERE TRAVELING
WITH A GROUP OF REBELS NEAR THE
BORDER WITH TURKEY AND
IRANIAN-TRAINED GUNMAN LOYAL TO
BASHAR AL-ASSAD AMBUSHED THEM,
EXECUTED AT LEAST ONE OF THE
REBELS, AND TOOK THEM INTO
CAPTIVITY.
>> THEY KEPT US BLINDFOLDED,
BOUND, WE WE WERE NOT PHYSICALLY
BEATEN, BUT PSYCHOLOGICAL
TORTURE, THREATS OF BEING
KILLED, SAYING WE WOULD HAVE TO
CHOOSE WHO WOULD BE SHOT FIRST.
>>Shepard: AS THEY WERE
BLINDFOLDED THEY WONDERED WHAT
WAS GOING ON.
RICHARD ENGEL SAYS THE GUNMAN
MOVED THEM TO A SAFE HOUSE AND
THERE WAS A FIREFIGHT AND ENGEL
AND THE CREW ESCAPED.
RICHARD AND HIS COLLEAGUES ARE
NOW SAFE AND IN TURKEY.
THE FOX REPORT CHIEF
CORRESPONDENT WITH THE NEWS.
THEY INSTITUTE ADD BLACKOUT OF
THIS NEWS OVER AT NBC BECAUSE
THEY.
WHATTED IT TRY TO GET THEM OUT
ALIVE SOMETHING WE HAVE DONE
WITH CORRESPONDENT WHOSE MET
WITH SIMILAR FATES TO THIS
NETWORK.
THANK GOD RICHARD ENGEL AND THE
CREW GET OUT.
>>Jonathan: WE OBSERVED THAT
BLACKOUT AT NBC REQUEST BUT A
TERRIFYING REQUEST FOR HIM AND
HIS COLLEAGUES.
IMAGINE THIS: 15 GUNMEN ALL
WEARING SKI MASKED AMBUSHED THEM
AND MOVED THEM CONSTANTLY BLIND
FOLDED AND HOODED FROM SAFE
HOUSE TO SAFE HOUSE.
THEY NEVER KNEW WHERE THEY WERE
AND THEN THE MOCK EXECUTIONS.
IMAGINE THE TERROR OF THAT.
YOU ARE HOODED.
THEY ASK WHICH YOU IS GOING DO
DIE.
FIRST YOU REFUSE TO GIVE AN
ANSWER.
AND YOU SIMPLY HEAR A RIFLE
BEING FIRED.
NOT SURPRISINGLY, ENGEL AND THE
OTHERS ALL SAY THEY SIMPLY WANT
TO PUT THE EXPERIENCE BEHIND
THEM.
>> THE LAST FIVE DAYS WERE VERY
DIFFICULT.
WE VERY HAPPY TO BE OUT.
WE ARE VERY HAPPY TO BE BACK IN
TURKEY.
WE LOVE BEING HERE.
WE LOVE THIS COUNTRY.
WE APPRECIATE ALL THE HELP.
THE LAST FIVE DAYS ARE DAYS WE
WOULD RATHER FORGET.
>>Jonathan: AS WE KNOW FROM
TALKING TO OTHER WHOSE HAVE BEEN
THROUGH SIMILAR SPENTS,
FORGETTING IS A VERY DIFFICULT
THING TO DO.
>>Shepard: HE HAS BEEN AN
OUTSTANDING COUNT, AND A GREAT
GUY, TOO.
>> ANOTHER JOURNALIST IS STILL
MISSING.
>>Jonathan: RICHARD ENGEL IS
WELL-KNOWN AND APPEARS ON NBC
NIGHTLY NEWS ALL THE TIME, BUT
THERE IS ANOTHER AMERICAN
JOURNALIST, A FREELANCER, A
WRITER FROM THE "WASHINGTON
POST" WHO HAS CONTRIBUTED, AND
HE IS A FORMER MAIN.
YOU MAY NOT HEARD OF 31 HAS NOT
BEEN HEARD FROM, SINCE AUGUST
13.
BELIEVED HELD IN SYRIA.
NO ONE KNOWS BY WHOM.
IT IS MOST LIKELY GOVERNMENT
FORCES BUT THEY DO NOT KNOW.
HIS PARENTS ARE DESPERATELY
TRYING TO GET NEWS OF HUM.
JUST ANOTHER DEMONSTRATION OF
HOW DANGEROUS SYRIA IS.
WE HAVE HAD COLLEAGUES THAT HAVE
BEEN KILLED THIS.
SYRIAN CIVILIANS, OF COURSE,
CONTINUE TO DIE EVERY DAY THIS.
>>Shepard: MORE THAN 40,000.
THANK YOU.
SYRIA'S LONG TIME ALLY, RUSSIA,
IS SENDING WARSHIPS TO SYRIA TO
PREPARE FOR THE POSSIBILITY OF
THE EVACUATION OF THEIR
CITIZENS.
THE REPORT FROM RUSSIAN STATE
MEDIA IS ANOTHER POTENTIAL SIGN
THAT NOW IS LOSING FAITH IN THE
SYRIAN REGIME.
LAST WEEK A TOP RUSSIAN DIPLOMAT
ADMITTED BASHAR AL-ASSAD COULD
LOSE THE CIVIL WAR.
WE HAVE THE FORMER DEFENSE
SECRETARY UNDER BILL CLINTON,
WILLIAM COHEN, THE CHAIRMAN AND
CHIEF EXECUTIVE OFFICER OF THE
COHEN GROUP.
NICE TO SEE YOU, SIR.
THIS WAS A TIME WHEN THERE WERE
RULES OF WARFARE, THERE WAS A
FRONT LINE, THERE WERE RULES
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENS TO THOSE WHO
GATHER AND GIVE OUT INFORMATION
BUT THERE ARE NO RULES NOW.
>>Guest: NO, WE HAVE NO RULES.
WE HAVE ENEMIES THAT ARE TOUGH
TO IDENTIFY.
THEY CAN BE WITH YOU DURING THE
DAY AS FRIENDLY AS WE HAVE SEEN
IN AFGHANISTAN AND THEN BE
ENEMIES AT NIGHT.
IT IS A DIFFERENT WORLD WE ARE
LIVING AND SYRIA IS A CLASSIC
EXAMPLE OF THIS TYPE OF WAR
UNDERWAY.
>>Jonathan: THE CHEMICAL
WEAPONS ARE A MAJOR CONCERN FOR
U.S. OFFICIALS AND THE STATE
DEPARTMENT SPOKESWOMAN SAID
THAT, SAYING THEY COULD FALL IN
THE HANDS OF THE REBELS AND THEY
COULD USE THEM.
WHAT DO WE DO ABOUT THE CHEMICAL
WEAPONS?
>>Guest: I AM SURE THAT THE
PENTAGON IS NOW REVIEWING ALL OF
THE CONTINGENCY OPERATIONS ON
THE BOARD, SO TO SPEAK.
THIS IS ONE OF THE REAL DANGERS
WE HAVE.
IF THE REBELS TAKE OVER, THEN
WHAT?
WHO ARE AMONG THE REBELS?
AL QAEDA ELEMENTS IN THERE?
SECURING THOSE PLACES WILL BE
VERY IMPORTANT.
IT WILL TAKE A LOT OF
INTELLIGENCE ANALYSIS.
WE WILL HAVE TO SHARE THAT
INFORMATION CERTAINLY WITH THE
ISRAELS, THE RUSSIANS WILL BE
VERY MUCH CONCERNED ABOUT IT.
ALL COUNTRIES SHOULD BE
CONCERNED ABOUT SHOULD THE
CHEMICAL OR BIOLOGICAL AGENTS
END UP IN THE HANDS OF TERRORIST
GROUPS.
WE ARE OUGHT AT RISK.
>>Jonathan: FOR SKEPTICAL
AMERICANS, HOW DO WE TRUST WHAT
WE ARE TOLD BY OUR OWN
OFFICIALS?
>>Guest: WELL, THE BAR OF
SKEPTICISM IS PRETTY HIGH FOR
MOST MEMBERS.
I CAN TELL YOU, WAY BACK IN THE
80'S WHEN I SERVED ON THE
INTELLIGENCE COMMITTEE IN THE
SENATE, I SAW EVIDENCE WE OF
WHAT THE SYRIANS WERE DOING WITH
THEIR NERVE AGENTS AND CHEMICAL
WEAPONS.
IT IS PRETTY DEALER THEY DO HAVE
THEM.
IT WAS ALSO CLEAR THAT IRAQ, IN
FACT, HAD THEM.
AND SADDAM HAD USED THEM.
SO WE KNOW THEY BEEN THIS THE
POSSESSION OF SADDAM HUSSEIN AT
ONE POINT.
WE BELIEVE THAT THE CHEMICAL
WEAPONS ARE STILL IN THE
POSITION OF THE SYRIAN
GOVERNMENT.
THAT IS A REAL DANGER WE HAVE TO
FOCUS ON, HOW DO WE SECURE THEM?
WE, WORKING WITH OTHER NATIONS
AND THE INTERNATIONAL COMMUNITY,
IF AT ALL POSSIBLE, TO MAKE SURE
THAT EITHER THE NUCLEAR WEAPONS
OR THE CHEMICAL AND BIOLOGICAL
WEAPONS DON'T FALL IN THE WRONG
HANDS.
>>Jonathan: MR. SECRETARY,
THANK YOU.
>>Shepard: THE PROSECUTION IS
CASTING A WIDE NET IN A
FRATERNITY HAZING DEATH.
POLICE SAY THEY HAVE TOLD 22
PEOPLE WHO KNEW THIS YOUNG MAN,
TURN YOURSELVES IN OR WE ARE
COMING FOR YOU.
THE CHARGES AND WHAT COULD
HAPPEN TO THE SUSPECTS NEXT.
[ Female Announcer ]
RESEARCH SUGGESTS CELL HEALTH
PLAYS A KEY ROLE
THROUGHOUT OUR LIVES.
One A Day Women's 50+
IS A COMPLETE MULTIVITAMIN
DESIGNED FOR WOMEN'S HEALTH
CONCERNS AS WE AGE.
IT HAS 7 ANTIOXIDANTS
TO SUPPORT CELL HEALTH.
One A Day 50+.
>> A FRESHMAN FRATERNITY PLEDGE
DIED AFTER AN ALCOHOL-FUELED
HAZING RITUAL.
NOW NECESSITY HAVE ISSUED ARREST
WARRANTS FOR 20 FRAT MEMBERS.
IT HAPPENED IN NORTHERN ILLINOIS
UNIVERSITY AT THE FRATERNITY.
ONE NIGHT LAST MONTH, THE
19-YEAR-OLD FRESHMEN WENT FROM
ROOM TO ROOM ANSWERING
QUESTIONS, AND IN EXCHANGE FOR
RIGHT ANSWERS HE GOT VODKA AND
OTHER LIQUOR.
THE NEXT MORNING HE WAS DEAD.
THE BLOOD ALCOHOL LEVEL CONTENT
WAS FIVE TIMES THE LEGAL LIMIT
FOR DRIVING.
A LAWYER FOR THE FAMILY SAYS
THAT THE STUDENT DID NOT HAVE A
CHOICE.
>> HE WANTED TO BE LIKED.
HE WANTED TO BE ACCEPTED.
THE TERMS OF THE GREAT CERTAINTY
WERE HE HAD TO GO THROUGH THIS.
>> THE FAMILY ARE NOT OUT FOR
REVENGE, BUT THAT SUCH DANGEROUS
RITUALS HAVE TO STOP.
THE FRATERNITY'S INTERNATIONAL
VICE PRESIDENT SAYS IT HAS
SUSPENDED THE CHAPTER AT
NORTHERN ILLINOIS UNIVERSITY AND
IS WORKING WITH POLICE TO GO
AFTER ANYONE WHO BROKE THE LAW.
THIS IS BUT THE LATEST DEATH IN
THE RESULT OF A HAZING INCIDENT.
POLICE IN FLORIDA SAY A DRUM
MAJOR DIED ON A SCHOOL BUS LAST
YEAR AFTER CLASSMATES PURGED AND
KICKED HIM DURING A RITUAL.
THE LIST IS LONG.
WE COULD GO ON THE WHOLE HOUR.
WE HAVE FORMER PROSECUTOR AND
CRIMINAL DEFENSE ATTORNEY WHO
HAS BEEN FOLLOWING THIS STORY.
WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT THIS?
I UNDERSTAND THIS IS A RITUAL
THAT HAD BEEN EMPLOYED FOR MANY
YEARS THERE.
IS THAT RIGHT?
OR IS THAT SPECULATION?
SHE CANNOT HEAR ME.
WE KNOW THIS HAS BEEN GOING ON
THERE FOR MAN YEARS ACCORDING TO
LOCAL REPORTING.
WE ARE WORKING TO IDENTIFY WHO
MIGHT HAVE BEEN INVOLVED WITH
THIS.
FIND OUT HOW LONG THE INCIDENTS
HAVE BEEN TAKING PLACE AND HOW
MANY OTHER VICTIMS OF THIS THERE
COULD HAVE BEEN.
THEY ARE ONLY LOOKING FOR THOSE
WHO MIGHT HAVE BROKEN THE LAW
AND THEY TOLD ALL THE STUDENTS
ON THE CAMPUS WHO WERE INVOLVED
TO COME FORWARD OR WE COMING
AFTER YOU.
THAT IS NORTHERN ILLINOIS
UNIVERSITY.
WE WILL HAVE UPDATES TONIGHT ON
FOX REPORT.
>> BIG NEWS FOR MILLIONS WHO USE
THE PHOTO SHARING SERVICE
INSTAGRAM.
THE COMPANY IS GIVING ITSELF THE
RIGHT TO SHARE YOUR PICTURES
WITHOUT ASKING YOU.
THE COMPANY IS GIVING ITSELF THE
RIGHT TO SELL YOUR PICTURES
WHETHER THE COMPANY ASKS YOU OR
NOT.
HOW MUCH DO YOU THINK THEY WILL
PAY YOU?
THAT IS AHEAD.
>> AND VIDEO OF THE MOMENT OF A
LANDSLIDE AND A MUDSLIDE THAT
SLAMMED RIGHT INTO A FREIGHT
TRAIN.
[ Sarah ] I THOUGHT,
THE RED CROSS DOES KATRINA.
THEY DON'T HELP SINGLE MOMS.
HI!
[ Sarah ] WHAT HAPPENED
TO OUR HOUSE LAST YEAR?
[ Daughters ] IT FLOODED
AND THE WATER FLOODED OUT. YEAH.
[ Sarah ] THE RED CROSS
ARRANGED THE HOTEL FOR US.
THEY GAVE ME THAT BREAK,
THAT LEVERAGE,
TO BE ABLE TO GET IT TOGETHER
AND TAKE CARE OF THEM. YOU KNOW?
I FEEL LIKE WE'VE COME
FULL CIRCLE.
[ Daughter 1 ] LIKE THAT!
[ Daughter 2 ]
THIS IS HOW I'LL DO IT.
[ Sarah ] THERE YOU GO.
>>Shepard: WE REPORTS
ON A HAZING INCIDENT THAT
RESULTED IN THE DEATH OF A
FRESHMAN STUDENT AND TRY TO MAKE
CONTACT WITH A DEFENSE ATTORNEY
BUT SHE HAS BEEN FOLLOWING THE
CASE CLOSELY AND BEEN ABLE TO
WORK THE AUDIO GLITCHES OUT.
IT IS MY UNDERSTANDING THIS HAS
BEEN GOING ON AT LEAST ACCORDING
TO LOCAL REPORTS, THERE, THIS IS
NOT NEW.
>>Guest: THIS IS NOT NEW.
THERE WAS A REPORTED CASE OF A
DEATH BACK IN THE 1990'S AND TO
THE SHE THAT THE FAMILY IS
HAVING IS THE UNIVERSITIES KNOW
ABOUT HAZING AND THEY HAVE NOT
DONE ANYTHING.
WHAT IS INTERESTING IS THE NEW
LAW ON HAZING DOESN'T REQUIRE
ANY CRIMINAL ACTIVITY AND IT IS
PUNISHABLE UP TO FELONY LEVEL.
>>Shepard: I REMEMBER A LOT
HAZING WHEN I WAS A STUDENT BUT
THAT DOESN'T HAPPEN ANYMORE
ACCORDING TO MY FRIENDS' KID BUT
AT NORTHERN ILLINOIS IT HAS
CONTINUED IS THE ACCUSATION.
WELL I GUESS WE CANNOT TALK TO
KELLY TODAY.
THEY ARE INVESTIGATING AND WE
WILL HAVE IT TONIGHT ON FOX
REPORT.
>> BIG PRIVACY CHANGES TO THE
PHOTO SHARING SERVICE CALLED
INSTAGRAM.
THE NEW POLICY LETS THEM SELL
THE PHOTOS THEY POST WITHOUT
TELLING YOU.
IF YOU USE THEM AND DON'T LIKE
IT, THEY DON'T CARE.
FACEBOOK PURCHASED THIS AND THEY
ARE ALLOWED TO SHARE AND EDIT
PHOTOGRAPHS ONLINE.
THE NEW POLICY READS YOU AGREE
THAT A BUSINESS OR OTHERWISE
ENTITY MAY PAY US TO DISPLAY
YOUR USER NAME LIKENESS PHOTOS
WITH ASSOCIATED DATA AND ACTIONS
YOU TAKE TO CONNECTION WITH PAID
OR SPONSORS CONTENT OR PROMOTION
WITHOUT COMPENSATION TO YOU.
IN OTHER WORDS, IF A USE ARE
TAKES A PICTURE OF A FORD
MUSTANG, THEY CAN IN THEORY AT
LEAST SELL THAT PHOTO TO FORD
AND ALLOW THEM TO USE IT AS AN
AD FOR THE MUSTANG AND NOT GIVE
YOU ANYTHING IN THE WAY OF
COMPENSATION.
ATA LOT USERS ARE REPORTING
OUTRAGE CALL THIS A SUICIDE
NOTE.
INSTAGRAM YOU JUST KILLED
YOURSELF.
WE REACHED OUT FOR FACEBOOK AND
THEY HAVE NOT REASONABLIED.
TRACE IS IN THE WEST COAST
NEWSROOM THIS IS ABOUT
GENERATING MORE ADVERTISING.
>>Trace: IT WOULD ALLOW
FACEBOOK TO ACCESS INSTAGRAM'S
ADVERTISING NETWORK, SO WHAT
HAPPENS IS IF YOU ARE
ADVERTISING ON FACEBOOK YOU HAVE
ACCESS TO ANYTHING I POST ON
INSTAGRAM.
YOU MENTIONED THE FORD MUSTANG
AND IF I TOOK A PICTURE OF THAT
YOU CAN USE THAT MUSTANG TO
ADVERTISE AND I WILL GIVE YOU
ONE BETTER.
IF I AM IN A RESORT WITH MY
FAMILY, I TAKE A WHOLE PICTURE
OF THE RESORT AND THE FAMILY AND
THEY COULD SELL THAT PICTURE,
FAMILY AND ALL, TO THE RESORT.
LEGAL EXPERTS SAY THEY MAY RUN
INTO A FEW PRIVACY LAWS.
>> YOU MAY HAVE RIGHTS AS A
MODEL DEPENDING ON YOUR STATE
BUT THIS CAN VARY FROM STATE TO
STATE AND IN SOME STATES YOU
WOULD STILL HAVE THE RIGHT TO
SUE INSTAGRAM AND CLAIM YOUR
LIKENESS BELONGS TO YOU AS A
MODEL IN THAT PICTURE FOR
PURPOSES OF COMMERCIAL SALE
ALTHOUGH THE PHOTOGRAPH MAY NOT.
>>Trace: AS A RULE YOU HAVE TO
BE 13 YEARS OLD TO SIGN UP FOR
INSTAGRAM BUT THE WAY THIS NEW
AGREEMENT WORKS YOU CAN BE ANY
AGE AND INSTAGRAM HAS THE RIGHT
TO USE YOUR PICTURE.
>>Shepard: CAN YOU OPT OUT?
>>Trace: YOU CAN'T.
YOU HAVE TO DELETE YOUR ACCOUNT.
THE PROGRAM SAYS THAT ONCE YOU
LOG ON TO INSTAGRAM THAT IS THE
HOW IT ENDS UP, YOU ARE THEIRS
AND YOU HAVE AGREED TO THE
TERMS.
INSTAGRAM SAYS THE CHANGES ARE
MAINLY TO HELP COMBAT SPAM BUT A
LOST USERS WE SPOKE WITH ARE
VERY SKEPTICAL.
>> I MIGHT HESITATE.
I AM NOT SURE HOW MUCH I WILL GO
TO NOT POSTING.
>> IT IS GETTING VERY SCARY WHAT
PEOPLE ARE DOING WITH PERSONAL
PICTURES.
IT MAKES ME THINK TWICE ABOUT
TAKING PICTURES AND POSTING
THEM.
>>Trace: INSTAGRAM AND
FACEBOOK DID NOT CAUSE YOU WILL
BUT THEY BOTH COMMENTED THIS
WILL BE GREAT FOR YOU.
>>Shepard: YOU ARE GOING TO
LOVE IT.
DRINK MORE.
TRACE, THANK YOU.
AND OUR SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY
EDITOR HAS MORE, AND THE WORD IS
"TRANSFERSABLE," WHICH IS THE
WORD OF INTEREST.
>>Guest: EXACTLY.
IT MAKES SENSE THEY WOULD WANT A
LICENSE TO YOUR CONTENT WHICH IS
SOMETHING THAT WAS ALREADY IN
THEIR AGREEMENT.
THE CHANGE ADS THAT WERE
"TRANSFERSABLE" WHO WILL THEY
TRANSFERS RIGHTS TO OUR PICTURES
TO?
THAT IS WHY PEOPLE HAVE FREAKED
OUT.
IF THEY TRANSFER THE PICTURE YOU
TOOK OF THE HUSBAND THANK TO
FORD AND GETTING BACK $5 THAT IS
UPSETTING FOR THE PERSON THAT
TOOK THE PICTURE.
IF I TOOK IT, IT WOULD BE A
EXTERNAL PHOTO BUT PROFESSIONAL
PHOTOGRAPHER WHOSE USE IT AND
RELY ON IT OR UPSET.
>>Shepard: A LOT OF
PROFESSIONALS WHO, SAY, YOU GO
TO A WEDDING AND YOU TAKE 300 OR
400 PICTURES AND RATHER THAN
PRINTING THEM AND GIVING THEM TO
PEOPLE OR SHOWING THEM YOU PUT
THEM ON INSTAGRAM AND THEY CAN
SAY, YES, WE WANT THIS OR THAT,
AND THEY CAN BE CHARGED FOR THE
ONES THEY GET.
>>Guest: THIS IS ONE POTENTIAL
OF A LOOSELY WRITTEN AGREEMENT.
>>Shepard: THEY COULD HAVE
SAID, WELL, THIS WAS NOT OUR
INTENT.
WE WILL GET THIS FIXED AND CALL
YOU RIGHT BACK.
>>Guest: I AM WITH YOU.
IT IS WEIRD.
WHY AREN'T THEY JUST SAYING
ANYTHING?
>>Shepard: THEY HAVE SAID A
LITTLE BIT.
>>Guest: SPAM IS THE PROBLEM
ON INSTAGRAM?
I DON'T THINK SO.
THEY ARE TRYING TO SELL ADS AND
TO DO THAT BY PUTTING UP MY
PICTURE, THAT IS THE PRICE OF A
FREE SERVICE BUT IF THEY LICENSE
MY PHOTOS THAT IS A PROBLEM.
THEY NEED TO SAY, NOS WE THOUGHT
DOING THAT AND THEY HAVE NOT
SAID THAT.
>>Shepard: IT IS FUNNY ALL OF
THE PRIVACY THINGS BASE WHAT YOU
HAVE DONE YOU HAVE TRUSTED YOUR
PROPERTY TO ANOTHER ENTITY TO
ALLOW YOUR FRIENDS OR WHATEVER
TO LOOK AT THEM AND YOU THOUGHT
MAYBE THAT ENTITY YOU
TRANSFERRED YOUR PROPERTY WASN'T
EVER GOING TO GET YOU.
DAD USED TO SAY IF IT SOUNDS TOO
GOOD TO BE TREE, IT PROBABLY IS.
THIS STUFF IS FREE.
>>Guest: TRACE TALKED TO
PEOPLE ON STREET SAYING THEY
WILL THINK TWICE ABOUT WHAT THEY
ARE DOING.
PLEASE, DO, YOU ARE GIVING AWAY
YOUR CON DIDN'T AND COMPLAINING
WHEN THEY USE IT.
>>Shepard: AND EVERYONE IS NOT
FULLY COLLECTED WHICH CREATES A
NEW PROBLEM.
>>Guest: THAT IS PARTLY THEIR
OWN FAULT.
>>Shepard: IT IS FULLY THEIR
HOW MANY HUNDREDS ARE THOUSANDS
OF PICTURES OF PEOPLE, WHO DO
NOT HAVE THEIR CLOTHES ON.
>>Guest: WHERE DO THOSE
PICTURES GO?
WE HAVE TO SEE WHAT THESE PEOPLE
DO WITH THIS.
THANK YOU.
NEW VIDEO IN FOX NEWS SHOWING A
MUDSLIDE PUSHING A MOVING TRAIN
OFF THE TRACK OF THE LOOK AT
THIS.
LOOK AT THIS.
JUST INCREDIBLE, HAPPENING
OUTSIDE SEATTLE.
AN OFFICIAL FOR THE TRAIN SAID
SEVEN CARS WERE DERAILED, SOME
CARRYING FERTILIZER AND CLEANING
AGENTS.
YOU WONDER WHY WHOEVER TOOK THE
CAMERA DID NOT STOP THE MUD BUT
THAT IS ANOTHER MATTER.
FORECASTERS SAY SNOW FALL IN THE
SOUTHWEST WILL TURN INTO A
BLIZZARD TOMORROW AS ITERATESES
TOWARD THE MIDWEST IN TIME FOR
SANTA.
JANICE DEAN, IT LOOKS LIKE SOME
COULD HAVE A VERY WHITE
CHRISTMAS.
>>Guest: THAT IS THE GOOD PART
BUT WE HAVE TO GET THROUGH
SEVERE WEATHER AND BLIZZARD IF
WEDNESDAY INTO THURSDAY.
SO, THE RADAR SHOWS A SYSTEM
EXITING THE NORTHEAST, WELL
AHEAD OF THE SYSTEM ACROSS THE
SOUTHWEST, SOME SNOW OVER THE
WESTERN GREAT LAKES AND UPPER
MIDWEST BUT THIS IS THE MAIN
EVENT ACROSS THE SOUTHWEST AND
IT WILL BRING 10" TO 20" OF SNOW
IF THE MOUNTAINS OF COLORADO
THROUGH WYOMING AND WINTER STORM
ADVISORIES STRETCHING FROM THE
SOUTHWEST ALL THE WAY UP TO THE
UPPER MIDWEST AND THE GREAT
LAKES AND WE HAVE BLIZZARD WANTS
AND WARNINGS FOR PARTS OF
COLORADO, KANSAS AND NEBRASKA
WITH HEAVY SNOW, AS WELL, ON TOP
OF WINDS GUSTING TO 50 MILES PER
HOUR.
WHERE IS THE STORM GOING?
WEDNESDAY INTO THURSDAY WE HAVE
6" TO 12" IN THE MIDWEST OF SNOW
AND THEN SEVERE WEATHER IN THE
MISSISSIPPI RIVER VALLEY PUSH
INTO THE EASTERN THIRD OF THE
COUNTRY BY THURSDAY INTO FRIDAY
AND IT WILL BE TOO WARM FOR SNOW
ACROSS WERE OF THE BIG CITIES
BUT LOOK AT THE SNOW AS WE HEAD
TOWARD THE UPPER MIDWEST HEADED
INTO FRIDAY, YES, CERTAINLY 6"
TO 12" AND 18" POSSIBLY IN
MILWAUKEE AREA.
GOOD NEWS FOR KIDS AND SNOW AND
SANTA BUT BAD NEWS IF YOU ARE
TRAVELING.
>>Shepard: THE LATEST OPEN
EGYPT'S POLITICAL CRISIS IS
NEXT.
[ fishing rod casting line,
marching band playing ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THE RHYTHM OF LIFE.
[ whistle blowing ]
WHERE DO YOU HEAR THAT BEAT?
CAMPBELL'S HEALTHY REQUEST SOUP
LETS YOU HEAR IT...
IN YOUR HEART.
[ basketball bouncing ]
HEART HEALTHY.
GREAT TASTE.
MMM...
[ Male Announcer ] SOUNDS GOOD.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
[ Male Annou♪ Music OUNDS GOOD.
Kids will spend
22 minutes watching us,
the Super Duper Party Troopers,
sing about ants in their pants.
Brushing for two minutes now,
can save your child from
severe tooth pain later.
Two minutes twice a day.
They have the time.
>>Shepard: PROTESTS IN EGYPT
DEMONSTRATING AGAINST PRESIDENT
MORSI AFTER THE FIRST ROUND OF
VOTING ON A DRAFT CONSTITUTION.
THE MEDIA REPORTS THAT OVER THE
WEEKEND 57 PERCENT OF PEOPLE
VOTED IN FAVOR OF THE DRAFT
WHICH THE OPPOSITION CLAIMS IS
TOO ISLAMIST AND LIMITS WOMEN'S
RIGHT OF FREE SPEECH.
OFFICIALS ARE INVESTIGATING
ACCUSATIONS OF WIDE-SPREAD VOTER
IRREGULARITY.
LELAND, WHAT KIND OF
IRREGULARITIES?
>>Reporter: EVERYTHING IF
STUFFING THE BALLOT BOX TO
SHOWING UP AT POLLING STATIONS
IN CHAOS BUT WE HAVE HEARD THE
ACCUSATIONS AFTER EVERY SINGLE
EGYPTIAN ELECTION.
COMPLICATING THING IS THE
ATTORNEY GENERAL RESIGNED MAKING
IT DIFFICULT FOR ANYONE TO
FIGURE OUT WHO WOULD INVESTIGATE
OR PROSECUTE THE CRIME.
WE ARE WILL SEEING THE SAME KIND
OF THINGS THAT ARE COMING OUT OF
THIS ELECTION WHICH IS PEOPLE
NOT HAPPY WITH THE RESULTS.
SO FAR, IN HALF OF THE COUNTRY,
57 PERCENT VOTED IN FAVOR OF THE
ISLAMIST CONSTITUTION WHICH IS
VERY STRONGLY WORDED IN TERMS OF
PRO ISLAMIST GOVERNMENT, AND THE
PRESIDENT OF EGYPT WAS IN FAVOR
AND THE LIBERALS HAVE COME OUT
STRONGLY AGAINST THIS
CONSTITUTION, COMING UP A SECOND
ROUND VOTING ON SATURDAY WHEN
THE REST OF THE COUNTRY VOTES.
HOWEVER, THE REST OF THE COUNTRY
IS LARGELY IN THE RURAL PART OF
THE COUNTRY BECAUSE THE MUSLIM
BROTHERHOOD WOULD BE A STRONGER
SHOWING COMING UP ON SATURDAY.
>>Shepard: AND WHAT HAPPENED
WITH THE PROTESTS SINCE THE
VOTE?
>>Reporter: WHEN VETO A AN
ELECTION PEOPLE DO NOT LIKE THE
RESULTS THEY TAKE TO THE STREETS
MUCH IT IS VIOLENT WITH TAMPS
SURROUND -- THANKS SURROUNDING
THE PALACE CHANTING "DOWN WITH
BROTHERHOOD RULE."
THE PEOPLE OUT PROTESTING ARE
THE ONES WHO ORIGINALLY STARTED
THE REVOLUTION, THE LIBERALS WHO
KICKED PRESIDENT MUBARAK OUT OF
OFFICE AND NOW THEY IS LAST
EVERY ELECTION SO FAR AND ARE
NOT ORGANIZED AND ARE BACK OUT
IN THE STREET.
SO FAR, THOUGH, PRESIDENT MORSI
HAS AHEAD ELECTIONS HAVE
CONSEQUENCES AND WE WON, AND SO
FAR WE ARE LEADING IN THE
REFERENDUM SO WE WILL CONTINUE
GOING DOWN THE PATH OF LEADING
EGYPT TOWARD A VERY STRONG LINE,
HARD-LINE ISLAMIST STATE.
>>Shepard: THE INSTABILITY IN
THE MIDDLE EAST CAN CERTAINLY
STOKE NEW FEARS OF TERRORISM
HERE ON OUR SHORES AND A FEDERAL
LAW ENFORCEMENT TRAINING CENTER
THE FEDS HAVE BEEN TEACHING LAW
ENFORCEMENT REGARDING CYBER
ATTACKS AND WEAPONS OF MASS
DESTRUCTION.
STEVE, WHAT KIND OF TACTICS DO
THEY EMPLOY HERE?
>>Reporter: ONE TACTIC IS A
DIFFICULT MANEUVER CALLED PIT
TRAINING, DURING HIGH SPEED
CHASE WITH CARS AND OTHER
PEOPLE.
BUT THIS, LIKE 7 OF THE TRAINING
WE ARE SEEING, IS DELIBERATELY A
HIGH STRESS SITUATION PUTTING
THE FEDERAL RESPONDERS IN THE
TOUGH SITUATIONS, REALLY, TO GET
THEM READY FOR WHAT COULD BE THE
REAL THING.
>>Shepard: THAT IS PRETTY
COOL.
DO THEY TIME THAT FOR THE CAMERA
S?
WE HAVE WATCHED THAT SORT OF
THING HAPPEN BEFORE.
THEY HAVE BEEN TRAINING ALL DAY
ON THIS STUFF?
>>Guest: THEY HAVE BEEN, ABOUT
60,000 AGENTS COME IN HERE
THROUGH THE COURSE OF A YEAR.
WE ARE SEEING SARIN GAS ATTACKS
SIMULATED, WITH LIE SPEED
CHASES, AND IT HAS BEEN
DESCRIBED AS DISNEY WORLD IF
COPS HERE AND FOR FEDERAL
AGENTS.
THEY ENENJOYING THE WORD.
>>Shepard: THEY ARE LENDING
HOW TO ANTICIPATE WHAT COULD
HAPPEN NEXT WITH SOMEONE WHO IS
IRRATIONALE?
>>Guest: ONE OF THE CONCERNS I
SAW HERE, WAS I.E.D. TRAINING,
AS WE HAVE SEEN IN AFGHANISTAN
AND IRAQ.
THE REASON FOR THE TRAINING
COULD BE FOR FEDERAL AGENTS  WHO
DO WORK OVERSEAS.
PART OF IT, ALSO, IS
ANTICIPATION AND TRYING TO
IMAGINE POTENTIAL ATTACKS HERE
IN THE UNITED STATES AND TO
PREPARE IF THEM BEFORE THEY HAVE
IT.
>>Shepard: THANK YOU, STEVE.
THE JUSTICE DEPARTMENT WILL NOT
FILE STALKING CHARGES AGAINST
THE MISTRESS OF THE FORMER CIA
CHIEF DAVID PETRAEUS ACCORDING
TO THE MISTRESS' ATTORNEY.
GENERAL PETRAEUS LAST MONTH
RESIGNED IN DISGRACE AFTER
ADMITTING HE HAD AN AFFAIR.
THE WHOLE THING CAME TO LIGHT
AFTER ANOTHER WOMAN WENT TO THE
F.B.I. AND CLAIMED THE MISTRESS
HAD THREATENED HER OVER E-MAIL.
THE FEDS INVESTIGATED BROADWELL
FOR CYBER STALKING AND THE
DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE HAS
DECLINED TO COMMENT.
>> WE HAVE LONG KNOWN THAT SOME
DRUGS CAN HAVE LIFE THREATENING
SIDE EFFECTS IF YOU TAKE THEM
WITH GRAPEFRUIT, RIGHT?
THERE WERE SOME DRUGS THEY DA
NOT INTERACT WELL.
NOW, RESEARCHERS SAY THE LIST IS
MUCH LONGER AND THERE ARE MANY
MORE MEDICINES THAT DO NOT NEED
TO GET ALONG WITH GRAPEFRUIT.
WE BREAKDOWN THE LIST IN A
MOMENT.
MORE ON HOW PARENTS ARE NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, ARE MOVING FORWARD
WITH TWO MOMS FROM SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>>Shepard: LEGISLATION IN
MICHIGAN WOULD ALLOW WITH EXTRA
TRAINING, PEOPLE TO CARRY
CONCEALED FIREARMS IN CHURCHES,
DAY CARES, AND SCHOOLS.
CONCEALED FIREARMS.
IN SCHOOLS.
THE MICHIGAN GOVERNOR SNYDER HAS
VETOED THAT LEGISLATION.
THAT WILL NOT GO INTO LAW IN THE
STATE OF MICHIGAN.
>> MORE NOW ON THE EFFORTS TO
RETURN TO NORMAL IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AFTER THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
WE HEAR FROM THE MOTHERS OF TWO
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
STUDENTS, ONE SURVIVED THE
ATTACK AND THE OTHER DID NOT GO
TO THAT SCHOOL ON FRIDAY.
AND MOLLY LINE SAYS THE MOMS ARE
READY TO GET THEIR KIDS
BACK-TO-SCHOOL.
>> EXACTLY.
THEY ALSO HAVE STUDENTS THAT GO
TO THE OTHER NEWTOWN SCHOOLS
THAT WENT TO CLASS TODAY SAYING
IT WAS GOOD TO GET THE KIDS FOLK
AND BOTH SUPPORT THE MOVE TO GO
TO THE NEW SCHOOL IN MONROE FOR
ALL THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
THE THIRD GRADER SURVIVED THE
MASSACRE THE HE WAS AT SCHOOL
AND BY THE END OF THE WEEK THEY
CAN LOOK AT THE NEW SCHOOL IN
MONROE.
AND KAREN'S SON WAS KEPT HOME
FROM SCHOOL ON FRIDAY, HE DOES
NOT KNOW HE HAS LOST FRIENDS
ONLY A BAD MAN CAME TO THE
SCHOOL AND HE IS ONE OF MANY
KINDERGARTENERS GATHERING TO BE
TOGETHER TO DO CRAFTS AND TO
HAVE HOLIDAY FUN BEFORE THE
SEASON GETS GOING, AND TO CREATE
A SENSE OF NORMALCY.
>> THEY ARE BABIES.
THE TEACHERS...THEY ARE HURTING,
AS WE ARE.
WE KNOW IT WILL BE HELPFUL TO
GET EVERYONE TOGETHER.
(INAUDIBLE).
>> THEY SHOULD GO BACK TO BE
WITH THEIR FRIENDS AND THEIR
CLASSROOM, BACK TO NORMAL, AND
TO HEAL TOGETHER AND TO
COMMUNICATE WITH EACH OTHER.
>>Reporter: THE WORD IS THE
SCHOOL IN MONROE, CHALK HILL,
WILL BE READY IN JANUARY.
>>Shepard: THANK YOU, MOLLY
LINE.
>> I AM WAITING FOR THIS THING
TO HAPPEN ON THE SCREEN, YOU
KNOW HOW IT DOES THAT?
BUT THIS IS NOT WORKING.
>> CAREFUL IF YOU ARE A FAN OF
GRAPEFRUIT.
THE LIT OF MEDICATIONS THAT
INTERACT IF A DANGEROUS WAY WITH
GRAPEFRUIT OR THE USE IS
GROWING.
RATHER, THEY ARE JUST FIGURING
OUT THAT NOW THEY ARE FIGURING
IT OUT INCLUDING KIDNEY FAILURE
AND THAT INCLUDES MEDICINE FOR
LOWERING CHOLESTEROL OR BIRTH
CONTROL PILLS.
AND NOW, WE HAVE A DOCTOR FROM
UNIVERSITY HOSPITAL OF
CLEVELAND.
I KNEW OF THIS WHEN NOT ALL THAT
LONG AGO I HAD TO TAKE...BLOOD
PRESSURE MEDICINE AND THEY ARE,
DO NOT EAT GRAPEFRUIT WITH THIS.
AND NOW THE LIST HAS GROWN.
>>Guest: THERE ARE 85 DRUGS ON
THE LIST AND OVER HALF CAN BE
ASSOCIATED WITH SERIOUS LIFE
THREATENING SIDE EFFECTS.
>>Shepard: WHAT HAPPENS IS, IT
IS NOT THAT THE DRUGS DO NOT GET
TO YOU, BUT IF MAN CASES THE
EFFECTS OF THE DRUGS COMPOUND
THEMSELVES?
HELP US UNDERSTAND.
>>Guest: WHAT HAPPENS IS
GRAPEFRUIT ACTIVATES AN ENZYME
SYSTEM THAT IS RESPONSIBLE FOR
BREAKING DOWN THE MEDICINES IN
YOUR BODY SO THE LEGALS DO NOT
RISE TOO HIGH SOEN WITH YOU
INCORRECT SMALL AMOUNTS OF GRAPE
TRUTH JUICE YOU CAN GET
DANGEROUSLY HIGH LEVELS OF THE
DRUG CAUSING THE SIDE EFFECTS IF
YOU TOOK TOO MUCH OF THE DRUG.
>>Shepard: SHOULD WE AVOID THE
JUICE IN GENERAL?
>>Guest: NO, I THINK
GRAPEFRUIT IS A HEALTHY
ALTERNATIVE TO SODA.
UNFORTUNATELY, SOME PEOPLE LIKE
IT SO MUCH THEY DRINK TOO MUCH
OF IT.
IF YOU TAKE A CERTAIN NUMBER OF
MEDICATION, ESPECIALLY
MEDICATIONS ON THE LIST, YOU
WILL BE AT HIGHER RISK FOR
DEVELOPING SIDE EFFECT.
>>Neil: WHY DOES IT DO THIS
AND NOT OTHER CITRUS JUICES?
>>Guest: THERE ARE OTHER
CITRUS FRUITS THAT ARE
ASSOCIATED WITH THIS, PROBABLY A
GOOD IDEA TO AVOID MOST CITRUS
INCLUDING LIME, LEMON AND SOME
ORANGES IF YOU ARE TAKING SOME
OF THE MEDICINES ON THE LIST.
IF YOU ARE GOING TO DRINK THE
BEVERAGES, JUST LIMIT IT TO ONE
OR TWO A WEEK.
>>Shepard: INTERESTING.
THE LIST IS ON OUR WEBSITE AND
IF ANYONE IS TAKING ANY OF
THOSE, ASK YOUR DOCTOR, THE LAST
THING YOU WANT IS YOUR MEDICINE
TO HARM YOU.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
>> IF YOU PLAN TO STEAL DIRECTOR
CHRISTMAS TREE FROM A PARK IN
NEW JERSEY YOU MAY GET A SMELLY
SURPRISE WHEN YOU TAKE IT HOME.
NOT A PINE SCENT.
NO, NOT AT ALL.
[ Male Announcer ] Alka-Seltzer
Plus PRESENTS THE Cold Truth.
I HAVE A COLD,
AND I TOOK NYQUIL,
BUT I'M STILL "STUBBED" UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT DOESN'T HAVE A DECONGESTANT.
NO WAY.
[ Male Announcer ] SORRY.
Alka-Seltzer Plus FIGHTS
YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A FAST ACTING
DECONGESTANT
TO RELIEVE YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
[ sighs ] THANKS!
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus.
♪ OH
WHAT A RELIEF IT IS! ♪
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
AND SAVE $1
VISIT Alka-Seltzer ON FACEBOOK.
Progresso.
In what world do potatoes,
bacon and cheese
add up to 100 calories?
Your world.
♪
[ whispers ]
Real bacon...
Creamy cheese...
100 calories...
[ Chef ] Ma'am
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
>>Shepard: A MAYOR OF A TOWN
IN SOUTH JERSEY HAS A NEW
STRATEGY TO END A CHRISTMAS
PROBLEM, GRINCHES CUTTING DOWN
EVERGREENS IN A PUBLIC PARK AND
MAKE THEY WILL CHRISTMAS TREES.
SO THEY ARE MAKING THE TREES
SMELL LIKE ROTTEN EGGS AND FISH.
THE MAYOR SAYS HE SPRAYED THE
EVERGREENS WITH A CHEMICAL THAT
MAKES THEM SMELL TERRIBLE WHEN
THEY REACT WITH A HEATED HOME.
>> THIS JUICE IS USED IN
FERTILIZER AND THIS IS MIXED
WITH THIS, WITH TWO COATS, AND
YOU GET 5 FOOT OF THE TREE YOU
DO NOT WANT IT IN YOUR LIVING
ROOM.
>>Shepard: AND NOW THE TREES
ARE NOT DISAPPEARIN