PRIME GERALDO WILL DO SPECIALS
AND JANINE PIRO WILL BE DOING
STUFF.
STAY WITH FOX NUSE CHANNEL
THROUGHOUT THE THE WEEKEND.
I AM SORRY I HAVE TO REPORT IT
HORRIBLE STORY SPOUT OFF ABOUT
THE FACTOR.
OREILLY NEWS.COM.
WORD OF THE DAY.
NO BILLINGS WHEN RUNNING THE
FACTOR.
I AM BILL O'REILLY.
REMEMBER THE SPIN HERE.
WE ARE DEFINITELY Y Y Y Y Y
♪
>> THIS IS A SATURDAY HE
EDITION OF "FOX & FRIENDS
FIRST."
I'M PATTI ANN BROWNE.
>> AND I'M HEATHER KNAUER.
IT IS SATURDAY, DECEMBER THE
15TH.
WE HAVE A FOX NEWS ALERT TO
BRING YOU RIGHT NOW.
AND THIS MORNING WE'VE LEARNED
MUCH MUCH MORE ABOUT THAT
AWFUL TRAGEDY THAT UNFOLDED
YESTERDAY IN NEWTOWN
CONNECTICUT.
20 CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS
GUNNED DOWN INSIDE AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL THERE.
FIRST, WE HAVE THE LATEST TIME
LINE EMERGING FROM THE TRAGEDY
AT ABOUT 9:30 A.M.
CLASSES BEGIN AT THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
IT'S KNOWN AS ONE OF THE
STATE'S TOP SCHOOLS.
SOME TEACHERS AND FACULTY
MEMBERS WERE GATHERED IN THE
MAIN OFFICE FOR A MEETING
ABOUT FIVE MINUTES LATER THEY
HEAR GUNSHOTS AND DUCK UNDER
TABLES.
THE SCHOOL'S PRINCIPAL DAWN
HOCKSPRUNG IS HER NAME AND
SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST CONFRONT
THE GUNMAN AND BECOME THE
SHOOTER'S VERY FIRST VICTIMS.
BEFORE SHE WAS KILLED, THE
PRINCIPAL LIKELY SAVED MANY
LIVES THERE BY TURNING ON THE
SCHOOL'S LOUD SPEAKER SO THAT
EVERYONE COULD HEAR AND THAT
EVERYONE COULD TAKE COVER IN
THAT SCHOOL.
SHORTLY AFTER, THE FIRST 911
CALL STARTED.
>> POLICE ARRIVED WITHIN
MINUTES.
AT 10:23 THEY ENTER THE SCHOOL
AND GO ROOM TO ROOM.
THEY CONFIRM THAT THE SHOOTER
IS DEAD.
AND THEY START MOVING CHILDREN
FROM HARM'S WAY.
>> FRANTIC PARENTS AND LOVED
ONES THEN STARTED TO RUSH TO
THE SCENE AND THEN LATER THAT
DAY, AFTER REWE REALIZED THE
MAGNITUDE OF THAT SHOOTING.
AT 3:17 PRESIDENT OBAMA
TALKING ABOUT THIS AS HE WIPES
AWAY HIS OWN TEARS AS HE
ADDRESSES THE NATION.
>> AN ENTIRE COMMUNITY IS NOW
MOURNING THIS NIGHTMARE OF A
TRAGEDY TOGETHER.
IN ALL, 26 CANDLES WERE LIT
AND THEN THEY WERE PLACED AT
AN ALTAR AT A MEMORIAL SERVICE
THAT TOOK PLACE LAST EVENING.
EACH ONE OF THOSE CANDLES FOR
ONE OF THE VICTIMS.
HUNDREDS FILLING SAINT ROSE OF
LIMA CATHOLIC CHURN.
THE CROWDS SPILLING OUTSIDE.
PEOPLE HUDDLING NEAR WINDOWS
TO REMEMBER THOSE INNOCENT
CHILDREN AND THE SCHOOL
FACULTY THAT WERE TAKEN FAR
TOO SOON.
>> WELL, PETER DOOCY IS LIVE
FOR US IN NEWTOWN THIS
MORNING.
HE HAS THE LATEST DEVELOPMENT
FOR US.
GOOD MORNING, PETER.
>> GOOD MORNING.
AND VERY SAD TO REPORT THAT
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER'S OFFICE
OHAS BEEN WORKING THROUGH THE
NIGHT INSIDE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE LAST UPDATE WE HAD LAST
NIGHT FROM THE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE IS THAT
AUTHORITIES HOPED TO
POSITIVELY IDENTIFY ALL OF THE
BODIES INSIDE BY TODAY.
SIX ADULTS AND 20 CHILDREN
WERE KILLED WHEN THE
20-YEAR-OLD MASS MURDERER,
9:30 A.M. AND FIRED ASD UP
MANY AS 100 SHOTS FROM AT
LEAST TWO PISTOLS, A GLOCK
MOSTLY INTO JUST TWO
CLASSROOMS.
TEACHERS DID THEIR BEST TO
SHIELD THEIR YOUNG STUDENTS'
EYES FROM THE UNTHINKABLE
SIGHTS IN THOSE CLASSROOMS.
WE HEARD HOW DEVASTATING THE
HUMAN TOLL WAS ON THE FIRST
911 CALLS.
MANY STUDENTS HEARD SCREAMS AS
YOU MENTIONED THROUGH THE
INTERCOM SYSTEM BEFORE THEY
WERE EVACUATED TO A NEARBY
FIREHOUSE.
THAT FIREHOUSE IS WHERE MOST
PARENTS WERE INSTRUCTED TO
SHOW UP YESTERDAY TO FIND OUT
IF THEIR CHILD HAD EVEN
SURVIVED.
AND LAST NIGHT AT A CHURCH
VIGIL IN THE TINY DOWNTOWN
AREA, NOT FAR FROM HERE.
WE TALKED TO SOME PARENTS WHO
TOLD US JUST HOW HARD IT WAS
NOT KNOWING BUT, AGAIN, THEY
EXPRESSED TO US THAT THEY FELT
TRULY BLESSED AND EVERYONE
THAT WE SPOKE TO SAID THAT
THEY KNOW SOMEONE WHO WAS NOT
ABLE TO PICK UP THEIR CHILD AT
THE FIREHOUSE YESTERDAY.
AND IT'S ALSO VERY SAD TO
REPORT THAT OUT OF EVERYONE
WHO WAS SHOT BY ADAM LANDS ZA
AT THE -- ALAN ZA.
THERE IS ONLY A SINGLE
SURVIVOR IT IS AN ADULT
FEMALE.
WE ARE EXPECTING TO HEAR MORE
INFORMATION A FEW STEPS AWAY
FROM ME FROM THE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE ABOUT THREE HOURS
FROM RIGHT NOW.
BACK TO YOU IN NEW YORK.
>> ALL RIGHT, THEY ARE NOW
QUESTIONING THE SUSPECT'S
FAMILY INCLUDING OLDER BROTHER
AND FATHER.
OLDER BROTHER WAS INITIALLY
MISTAKEN AS THE SHOOTER.
THE KILLER AND HIS OLDER
BROTHER HAVE REPORTEDLY BEEN
ESTRANGED FOR THE LAST TWO
YEARS.
ANNA KOOIMAN JOINS US NOW.
SHE IS ON THE PHONE.
SHE IS ON THE WAY TO HOBOKEN,
NEW JERSEY.
POLICE SEARCHING HIS HOME.
WHAT YOU CAN TELL US TODAY?
>> GOOD MORNING, HEATHER.
WE ARE ACTUALLY HERE ON SCENE.
IT IS VERY QUIET NOW JUST
AFTER 10:00 LAST NIGHT WE DID
WATCH AS COPS ROLLED UP.
POLICE TAPE WRAPPED AROUND
THAT BUILDING.
THAT IS OF COURSE WHERE THE
BROTHER LIVES WITH TWO OTHER
PEOPLE WE'RE TOLD.
STREETS IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD
WERE BLOCKED OFF EARLIER
YESTERDAY.
THE FBI AND HOBOKEN POLICE ON
SCENE.
RESIDENTS SAYING THAT A BOMB
SQUAD WAS GOING THROUGH THE
HALLWAYS OF THEIR BUILDING.
A FEDERAL SOURCE TELLS US
YESTERDAY RYAN LANZA ROLLED UP
POLICE SURROUNDING THE
BUILDING HANDCUFFED AND TAKEN
AWAY.
CONFUSION OVER THE IDENTITY OF
THE ACTUAL SHOOTER BECAUSE
ADAM WAS CARRYING RYAN'S I.D.
ALL SORTS OF RUMORS FLYING
THERE.
WERE REPORTS THAT SOMEONE WAS
POSSIBLY DEAD INSIDE, MAYBE
EVEN THE FATHER PETER LANZA.
FBI SOURCE SAYING HE IS ALIVE
AND WAS QUESTIONED YESTERDAY.
PETER LANZA AND THE BOY'S
MOTHER ARE DIVORCED.
PETER WE MARRIED WE'RE TOLD
AND LIVES IN STANFORD,
CONNECTICUT AND HEATHER, THE
FBI SAYING THAT THE BROTHER
AND FATHER HAVE BEEN CLEARED
AND THEY ARE NO LONGER BEING
QUESTIONED.
ALTHOUGH NOT A SUSPECT, RYAN'S
COMPUTER AND PHONE RECORDS ARE
BEING SEARCHED AND REPORTS SAY
THAT RYAN DID TELL LAW
ENFORCEMENT YESTERDAY THAT HE
HAD NOT BEEN IN TOUCH WITH HIS
BROTHER ADAM SINCE ABOUT 2010.
MENTIONED ADAM POSSIBLY HAVING
A PERSONALITY DISORDER AND
MILD AUTISM.
AND ALSO AS RYAN WAS GOING
THROUGH ALL OF THIS YESTERDAY
AND WATCHED EVERYTHING UNFOLD
ON TUITION, HE WAS POSTING ON
FACEBOOK HEY, IT WASN'T ME.
I WAS AT WORK.
HE REALLY HAS GONE THROUGH A
LOT.
LASTLY, RESIDENTS OF HOBOKEN
HAVE BEEN THROUGH A WHOLE LOT.
THEY WERE REALLY RATTLED AND
CONTINUED TO BE YESTERDAY DAY
CARE WAS ON LOCKDOWN THEY
EVERYWHERE GETTING EMAILS
ABOUT THEIR CHILDREN BEING
INSIDE AND JUST AFTER WATCHING
EVERYTHING UNFOLD, YOU KNOW,
NOT TOO FAR AWAY, THIS WAS
DEFINITELY A TOUGH SITUATION
FOR THEM, HEATHER.
>> THANK YOU.
ANNA KOOIMAN ON HER WAY TO
HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY THIS
MORNING.
EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT OBAMA
REACTING TO THE SENSELESS
MURDERS.
FOR MORE ON THE PRESIDENT'S
REACTION.
LET'S GO LIVE TO OUR CHIEF
WASHINGTON CORRESPONDENT JAMES
ROSEN IN WASHINGTON.
>> FROM THE CAPITOL WHERE
PRESIDENT OBAMA AS FOR ALL
AMERICANS YESTERDAY WAS AS IF
THE MADNESS OF THE PHENOMENON
WE HAVE COME TO CALL THE MASS
SHOOTING FINALLY DESCENDED
NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT TO
CRUELEST, MOST HORRIFYING
LEVEL.
THE PROFILE OF THE YOUNG MAN
STILL IN ADOLESCENCE, DEEPLY
SEVERED FROM ANY SENSE OF
COMMUNITY AND LIFEEST SIMPLEST
PLEASURES.
POCKET PROTECTER IN HIGH
SCHOOL.
ADVANCED INTELLIGENCE BUT
REMOTE.
MOST OF THE VICTIMS VERY
DIFFERENT.
CHILDREN RANGING IN AGE 5 TO
10.
THE MOST DEFENSELESS THAT WALK
AMONG US.
THE GRIM TOLL AS WE HAVE BEEN
REPORTING 28 DEAD.
THE MOTHER.
THE SCHOOL'S PRINCIPAL AND 20
CHILDREN.
ONE SCHOOL WORKER DOOCY
REPORTED WAS WOUNDED.
PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS PLAYED
CONSOLER IN PAST STRUGGLED
THIS TIME TO CONTAIN HIS
EMOTIONS OF THE NEWS.
SPOKE OF THE LANDMARKS IN
LIFE.
BIRTHDAYS, CHILDBIRTH THAT THE
VICTIMS AND THEIR FAMILIES
WERE ROBBED OF ALONG WITH THE
INNOCENCE TAKEN TOO EARLY FROM
THOSE WHO SURVIVED.
WE HAVE ENDURED TOO MANY OF
THESE TRAGEDIES IN THE PAST
FEW YEARS HE SAID AND EACH
TIME I LEARN THE NEWS I REACT
NOT AS A PRESIDENT BUT AS
ANYBODY ELSE WOULD AS A
PARENT.
THE PRESIDENT ALSO SPOKE OF
THE NEED FOR THE QUOTE UNQUOTE
MEANINGFUL ACTION TO ADDRESS
THESE KINDS OF INCIDENTS BUT
HE OFFERED NO SPECIFICS.
FLAGS AT THE WHITE HOUSE AND
THE CAPITOL BUILDING ARE
FLYING AT HALF-STAFF ACROSS
AND AT EVERY LEVEL OF THE
SPORTS WORLD, MOMENTS OF
SILENCE WAS OBSERVED.
IT IS AND WILL BE A BITTER
HANUKKAH AND CHRISTMAS FOR
AMERICA THIS 2012.
PATTI ANN AND HEATHER.
>> SO SAD.
JAMES ROSEN LIVE IN
WASHINGTON.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH
OUR CONTINUING COVERAGE OF THE
SCHOOL TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT.
>> COMING UP NEXT, A CHILD
PSYCHOLOGIST JOINS US AFTER
THE BREAK WITH A LOOK AT WHAT
COULD HAVE BEEN GOING THROUGH
THE MINDS OF THOSE CHILDREN
TRAPPED INSIDE THAT SCHOOL AS
THE MASSACRE UNFOLDED.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
>> IN MY MIND I'M THINKING AS
A 6-YEAR-OLD, 7-YEAR-OLD, WHAT
ARE YOUR THOUGHTS?
I'M THINKING THAT I HAVE TO
PARENT.
I HAVE TO TELL THEM.
I SAID TO THEM I NEED YOU TO
KNOW THAT I LOVE YOU ALL VERY
MUCH AND THAT IT'S GOING TO BE
OKAY.
BECAUSE I THOUGHT THAT WAS THE
LAST THING THEY WERE EVER
GOING TO HEAR.
>> THAT TEACHER KATELYN ROIG
PROTECTED THOSE STUDENTS BY
LOCKING THEM IN A BATHROOM AND
TELLING THEM TO BE AS QUIET AS
POSSIBLE.
AUGUST THE WHILE THEY COULD
HEAR GUNSHOTS ON THE OTHER
SIDE OF THE DOOR.
DID THEY REALIZE WHAT WAS
HAPPENING AND WHAT ABOUT THE
OLDER KIDS.
WE ARE JOINED BY DR. JENNY
KLEIN.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
>> MY PLEASURE.
>> YOU HAVE THE TEACHERS
TRYING TO STAY CALM.
IT'S OBVIOUS THAT THEY ARE
VERY EMOTIONAL AS WELL.
EVEN THE YOUNGER KIDS WHO
MIGHT NOT BE ABLE TO
COMPREHEND THE SPECIFICS OF
WHAT'S HAPPENING.
THEY ARE FEELING THAT EMOTION.
>> OH, ABSOLUTELY.
KIDS HAVE ARE EITHER MAD,
SCARED, SAID OR HAPPY.
THEY HAVE ENORMOUS IMAGINATION
FOR POWER WHEN THEY DON'T HAVE
ANY.
>> THAT'S INTERESTING YOU SAY
THAT BECAUSE ONE TEACHER WAS
TELLING HER YOUNGER KIDS THERE
IS A BAD GUY OUTSIDE.
WE HAVE TO STAY VERY QUIET
INSIDE.
AND ONE OF THE KIDS SAID OH I
KNOW KARATE, IT'S OKAY.
I WILL LEAD US ALL OUT OF
HERE.
>> THAT'S THE IMAGINATION
BEFORE POWER TO PROTECT.
THEY DON'T REALLY HAVE IT AND
THEN THEY HATE THEMSELVES.
AND THERE IS NO TIME IN THE
MIND SO THEY WILL BURY THAT
EXPERIENCE.
>> AS THE TEACHERS AND THE
OTHER STAFF WERE TRYING TO
PROTECT THESE KIDS, THEY DON'T
WANT TO CONVEY JUST HOW
HORRIFIC THIS SITUATION IS BUT
AT THE SAME TIME, IT IS VERY
IMPORTANT THAT THEY CONVEY
SOME SENSE OF DANGER SO THAT
THE KIDS TAKE THIS SERIOUSLY.
HOW DO YOU WALK THAT LINE?
>> WELL, IT'S REALLY --
CHILDREN WILL FEELINGS AND
EXPRESSIONS ON THEIR FACES HOW
SERIOUS IT IS AND FROM THEIR
OWN FEAR THEY WILL KNOW IT IS
VERY SERIOUS.
>> SO THEY CAN SENSE THE FEAR?
>> TEACHERS ARE SCARED AND
THEY ARE BIG PEOPLE SO IT MUST
BE SERIOUS.
>> REPORTS THAT THE PRINCIPAL
TURNED ON THE INTERCOM IN
ORDER TO WARN EVERYBODY THAT
THIS WAS UNFOLDING.
CREDITED FOR SAVING LIVES FOR
DOING THAT AT THE SAME TIME
THIS MEANT THAT THESE STUDENTS
HEARD SCREAMS IN ADDITION TO
THE GUNSHOTS.
HOW WOULD THEY BE PROCESSING
THAT?
>> WELL, THEY WILL HEAR THEM
AND THEY WILL BE IN THEIR MIND
FOREVER BECAUSE THERE IS NO
TIME IN THE MIND.
SO WHENEVER THEY ARE 44 AND
THEY HEAR A SCREAM, THEY WILL
GO BACK TO WHEN THEY WERE VERY
LITTLE AND BRING UP THE FEAR
AND THE TERROR.
THAT'S WHAT HAPPENS IN THE
MIND.
THERE IS NO TIME IN THE MIND
AT ALL.
>> YEAH.
SO YOU HAVE GOT KIDS IN THE
SCHOOL RANGING FROM
KINDERGARTEN UP TO FOURTH
GRADE.
OBVIOUSLY A DIFFERENCE BETWEEN
HOW A 5-YEAR-OLD PROCESSES
THIS VERSUS A 10-YEAR-OLD.
ONE OF THE 3RD GRADERS SAID
SHE THOUGHT SHE WAS GOING TO
THROW UP.
VERY AFRAID AND MUCH MORE REAL
FOR THEM.
HOW WOULD THE OLDER KIDS BE
PROCESSING THIS?
>> WELL, THEY WILL PROCESS
THEIR FEELINGS AND THEY WILL
USE A LITTLE BIT OF THEIR
LOGIC SO TO SPEAK.
WHATEVER IS IN THEIR
IMAGINATION FOR THE -- TO FILL
IN THE POWER THEY NEVER HAD
WHEN THEY WERE SMALL BECAUSE
THEY CREATE THAT IS GOING TO
COME DOWN AND BLAME THEMSELF
FOR NOT BEING ABLE TO DO
ANYTHING.
>> YOU ARE SAYING THAT THEY
ARE ACTUALLY GOING TO BE
FEELING A GUILT AFTERWARDS?
>> YES.
WE ALL IMAGINE A SELF-WITH
INFINITE POWER LOCK, MOMMY,
CAN I FLY.
AND THEN IT DESSENDS INTO OUR
UNCONSCIENCE MIND 90% OF YOUR
BRAIN AND THE SPEED OF
PROCESSING THAT IS ENORMOUS
MORE SO THAN YOUR CONSCIENCE
MIND WHICH IS 10% OF YOUR
BRAIN.
WHAT HAPPENS IS SOMETHING
HAPPENS MANY YEARS LATER AND
IN TWO SECONDS, IT TRIGGERS
THAT FEAR AND THAT MEMORY AND
THAT SELF-HATE FOR BEING
POWERLESS AS OPPOSED TO THE
INFINITE POWER I WISH I HAD
THEN.
AND I DIDN'T.
>> SO, THEY HAVE GOT YEARS
AHEAD OF THEM OF HOPEFULLY
GETTING HELP AND PROCESSING
THIS AND FORGIVING THEMSELVES
AND MOVING ON.
>> MOST IMPORTANT THING IS TO
TEACH PEOPLE HOW THEIR MIND
WORKS.
WE NOW HOW OUR COMPUTER WORKS
BUT THEY DON'T KNOW THAT THE
HARD DRIVE OF OUR MIND
COLLECTS EVERYTHING WE HAVE
EVER EXPERIENCED AND IT
COMPARES US TO THE REALITY OF
OUR POWER, WHICH IS MUCH LESS.
THAT'S WHERE SELF-HATE GETS
STORED INSIDE AND COMES OUT
LIKE THIS KILLER IN KILLING
HIS MOTHER AND THEN KILLING
THE KIDS IN HER CLASS.
AND THEN KILLING HER KID WHICH
IS HIMSELF.
>> WE HAVE TO LEAVE IT THERE
BUT A LOT OF WORK TO BE DONE
AFTER THIS TRAGEDY.
DR. JENNY KLEIN THANK YOU SO
MUCH.
>> OUR PLEASURE.
>> WHEN WE COME BACK, THERE
ARE REPORTS THAT THE SHOOTER
SUFFERED FROM PERSONALITY
DISORDER.
THIS IS NOW THE FOURTH MASS
SHOOTING THIS YEAR AND PEOPLE
ARE ASKING IS THE COUNTRY
FACING AN EPIDEMIC?
>> RESPONDING AT THIS TIME.
THE SHOOTING APPEARS TO HAVE
STOPPED.
THE SCHOOL IS IN LOCKDOWN.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'VE REACHED THE AGE
WHERE YOU DON'T BACK DOWN
FROM A CHALLENGE.
THIS IS THE AGE OF KNOWING
HOW TO MAKE THINGS HAPPEN.
SOWHY LET
ERECTILE DYSFUNCTION
GET IN YOUR WAY?
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT VIAGRA.
20 MILLION MEN ALREADY HAVE.
ASK YOUR DOCTOR IF YOUR HEART
IS HEALTHY ENOUGH FOR SEX.
DO NOT TAKE VIAGRA IF YOU TAKE
NITRATES FOR CHEST PAIN;
IT MAY CAUSE AN UNSAFE DROP
IN BLOOD PRESSURE.
SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE
HEADACHE, FLUSHING,
UPSET STOMACH,
AND ABNORMAL VISION.
TO AVOID LONG-TERM INJURY,
SEEK IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
FOR AN ERECTION
LASTING MORE THAN FOUR HOURS.
STOP TAKING VIAGRA
AND CALL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU EXPERIENCE
A SUDDEN DECREASE OR LOSS
IN VISION OR HEARING.
THIS IS THE AGE
OF TAKING ACTION.
VIAGRA.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR.
>> WE'RE GOING TO ANSWER ALL
THOSE QUESTIONS.
WE WILL DO EXTENSIVE
BACKGROUND ON THE SHOOTER AS
FAR AS WE NEED TO GO.
WE WILL ANSWER THE QUESTION
ABOUT THE HISTORY AND ANY
HISTORICAL EVENTS THAT THIS
YOUNG MAN MAY HAVE BEEN
INVOLVED IN.
>> WE EXPECT TO LEARN A LOT
MORE TODAY ABOUT THE SHOOTER'S
BACKGROUND.
AND THERE ARE REPORTS SO FAR
THAT HE SUFFERED FROM SOME
SORT OF PERSONALITY DISORDER.
FOX NEWS MEDICAL A TEAM
DR. DAVID SAMADI JOINS US THIS
MORNING.
GOOD MORNING.
>> GOOD MORNING.
>> WE ARE HEARING FROM HIS
OLDER BROTHER THAT HE SUFFERED
FROM SOME SORT OF PERSONALITY
DISORDER.
OTHERS ARE SAYING HE WAS
RECLUSIVE.
HE WAS QUIET.
WHAT DOES THAT TELL YOU ABOUT
HIM.
>> MORE AND MORE INFORMATION
IS COMING ABOUT THE SHOOTER.
THERE IS A DISCUSSION THAT
PERHAPS HE HAD SOME SORT OF AS
BERGER'S OR EVEN WAS DIAGNOSED
WITH AUTISM.
NOW, IT'S VERY IMPORTANT TO --
I JUST WANT TO GET THIS OUT,
WE ARE NOT SAYING THAT AUTISM
CAUSES THIS KIND OF BEHAVIOR.
THE FACT THAT HE WAS A LOANER,
HE WAS NOT INVOLVED IN ANY
SOCIAL INTERACTION.
CAN'T KEEP A REAL
CONVERSATION.
WHEN THEY TALK TO A LOT OF HIS
FRIENDS THEY FOUND OUT HE WAS
ALWAYS BY HEIMSELF.
HE WASN'T ENGAGING IN ANY
GAMES.
SO THE BEHAVIOR WAS NOT REALLY
NORMAL.
>> NOT THAT OF A TYPICAL
20-YEAR-OLD?
>> EXACTLY RIGHT.
NOW WE ARE SEEING MORE AND
MORE OF THESE PEOPLE COMING TO
MOVIE THEATERS AND COMING TO
SCHOOLS AND GO ON RAMPAGE AND
START KILLING PEOPLE THERE IS
A DEVELOPMENTAL PROBLEM WITH
THEIR BRAIN AND THEY DON'T
TREAT PEOPLE, YOU KNOW, THEY
TREAT THEM LIKE AN OBJECT.
SO FOR HIM TO SHOOT HIS MOM,
COME TO SCHOOL AND START
SHOOTING ALL THESE KIDS, THERE
IS OBVIOUSLY HE DOESN'T
PROCESS THE INFORMATION THE
SAME WAY THAT YOU AND I DO.
HE MAY NOT LOOKING AT THE KIDS
AS A PERSON.
SO THESE ARE THE VERY
DIFFICULT ISSUES THAT HAS TO
BE DEALT WITH EARLY ON AND
MAYBE SEEK HELP BEFORE WE SEE
THIS KIND OF TRAGEDY.
>> YOU FEEL THERE MAY HAVE
BEEN SIGNS LEADING UP TO THIS,
SOME SIGNS THAT OTHER PEOPLE
MIGHT HAVE NOTICED.
>> IF YOU REALLY GO BACK AND
START ASKING A LOT OF PEOPLE
THAT WERE AROUND HIM, THERE IS
ALWAYS SIGNS AND SYMPTOMS OF
THIS KID REALLY HAVING
ABNORMAL BEHAVIOR.
NOT WITH IT, TOTALLY DIFFERENT
AND SO, YES, IT'S ALWAYS
THERE.
WE MAY OR MAY NOT PAY
ATTENTION BECAUSE SOMETIMES
YOU MAY FEEL SORRY OR, YOU
KNOW, THERE ARE ALWAYS.
>> AT 20 YEARS OLD HE IS AN
ADULT.
THE LAWS IN THIS COUNTRY
PRO-INDIVIDUAL.
DIFFICULT FOR A FAMILY TO TRY
TO FORCE ANY KIND OF TREATMENT
UPON SOMEBODY.
>> YOU ARE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
I THINK CATCHING THIS EARLY ON
BEFORE THEY GET TO THAT AGE IS
ABSOLUTELY CRITICAL.
I THINK AS A COUNTRY WE ARE
GOING THROUGH A VERY TOUGH
TIME.
I HOPE WE DON'T SEE MORE AND
MORE OF THESE ISSUES.
BUT AS THE PRESSURE, WHETHER
IT'S ECONOMIC OR FAMILY ISSUES
AND OTHER CASES LIKE THIS MAY
BECOME MORE APPARENT.
I THINK SPENDING TIME WITH THE
FAMILY, CATCHING THEM EARLY,
DIAGNOSING THEM EARLY IS THE
WAY TO GO.
>> JUST BRIEFLY WE ARE HEARING
ABOUT THESE WHITE MIDDLE CLASS
YOUNG MEN WHO ARE DOING.
THIS WHAT DOES THAT TELL US?
>> I DON'T THINK THAT, YOU
KNOW, THERE IS ANYTHING --
WHETHER THEY ARE WHITE OR NOT.
I THINK JUST OVERALL, YOU
KNOW, LOOKING AT TEENAGERS
LIKE THIS, THEY ARE GOING
THROUGH A VERY TOUGH TIME.
I DON'T WANT TO JUDGE THIS AT
THIS POINT.
I THINK IT'S EARLY ON IN THE
INVESTIGATION.
WE NEED TO SPEND A LITTLE MORE
TIME TO FIND OUT WHAT'S GOING
ON.
SO, AS A STORY DEVELOPS AND WE
FIND OUT MORE WE WILL GET TO
THE BOTTOM OF THIS.
>> DR. DAVID SAMADI PART OF
OUR MEDICAL A TEAM THANK YOU
FOR COMING ON THIS MORNING.
WE WILL BE BACK IN A FEW
MINUTES
MINUTES WITH OUR CONTINUING
COVERAGE IN CONNECTICUT.
HARD TO IMAGINE HOW FAMILIES
HANDLE A LOSS LIKE THIS.
COMING UP, WE WILL WILL SPEAK
WITH ONE MOTHER WHOSE DAUGHTER
DIED AND HER SON SURVIVED THE
COLUMBINE MASSACRE.
[ Male Announcer ] THIS IS
JOE WOODS' FIRST DAY OF WORK.
AND HIS NEW BOSS TOLD HIM
TWO THINGS --
COOK WHAT YOU LOVE,
AND SAVE YOUR MONEY.
JOE DOESN'T KNOWT YET,
BUT HE'LL WORK HIS WAY UP
FROM BUSSER TO WAITER TO CHEF
BEFORE OPENING A RESTAURANT
SPECIALIZING IN FISH AND GAME
FROM THE GREAT NORTHWEST.
HE'LL START INVESTING EARLY,
HE'LL FIND SOME GOOD PEOPLE
TO HELP GUIDE HIM,
AND HE'LL SET MONEY ASIDE
FROM HIS FIRST DAY OF WORK
TO HIS LAST,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
AT LEGALZOOM, WE'VE CREATED
A BETTER PLACE
TO HANDLE YOUR LEGAL NEEDS.
MAYBE YOU HAVE QUESTIONS
ABOUT INCORPORATING
A BUSINESS
YOU'D LIKE TO START.
OR QUESTIONS
ABOUT PROTECTING YOUR FAMILY
WITH A WILL OR LIVING TRUST.
AND YOU'D LIKE TO FIND
THE RIGHT ATTORNEY
TO HELP GUIDE YOU ALONG,
ANSWER ANY QUESTIONS
AND OFFER ADVICE.
WITH AN "A" RATING FROM
THE BETTER BUSINESS BUREAU
LEGALZOOM HELPS YOU GET
PERSONALIZED AND AFFORDABLE
LEGAL PROTECTION.
IN MOST STATES, A LEGAL PLAN
ATTORNEY IS AVAILABLE WITH
EVERY PERSONALIZED DOCUMENT
TO ANSWER ANY QUESTIONS.
GET STARTED AT LEGALZOOM.COM
TODAY.
AND NOW YOU'RE PROTECTED.
>> YOU ARE WATCHING "FOX &
FRIENDS FIRST."
I'M PATTI ANN BROWNE.
I AM HEATHER NAUERT.
IT IS NOW PAST THE HOUR.
OUR COVERAGE OF THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY IN NEW TOWN,
CONNECTICUT CONTINUES THIS
MORNING.
OVERNIGHT WE ARE LEARNING A
LOT OF NEW DETAILS ABOUT THAT
HORRIFIC TRAGEDY.
IT TOOK JUST MINUTES FOR THE
GUNMAN TO MURDER 20 CHILDREN
AND 6 SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL MEMBERS.
>> THE DAY STARTED LIKE ANY
OTHERS, 9:30 THE CLASS BEGAN
WITH THE DOORS OF THE SCHOOL
LOCKED.
FACULTY MEMBERSY IN THE OFFICE
FOR MEETING.
SHOTS RUNG OUT.
>> RUSHED TO THE AREA, THAT'S
WHEN THE SHOOTER OPENED FIRE
ON HIM AND THEY WERE HIS FIRST
VICTIMS.
PLAYING OUT OVER OFFICE LOUD
SPEAKER THAT'S WHERE THE
ENTIRE SCHOOL HEARD THAT CHAOS
AS IT UNFOLDED.
SHORTLY THEREAFTER THE CALLS
FOR HELP THEN STARTED.
>> WE HAVE MULTIPLE WEAPONS,
INCLUDING LONG RIFLES AND SHOT
GUNS.
WE NEED OFFICERS HERE.
SAAT CALL DAN BURY IF YOU HAVE
TO.
>> GOING ROOM TO ROOM SEARCH
FOR THE SHOOTER FOUND DEAD
INSIDE A CLASSROOM.
THAT'S WHEN OFFICERS BEGAN TO
MOVE STUDENTS AND STAFF OUT.
>> FRANTIC PATIENCE AND OTHER
LOVED ONES RUSHING TO THE
SCENE HOPING TO FIND THEIR
CHILDREN SAFE AND SOUND.
>> THERE IS NO WORDS.
THERE IS NO WORDS.
IT'S SHEAR TERROR AND A SENSE
OF IMMEDIATE URGENCY AND, YOU
KNOW, TO GET TO YOUR CHILD AND
TO BE THERE TO PROTECT THEM.
>> LATER IN THE DAY AT 3:17.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WIPING AWAY
TEARS AS HE ADDRESSES THE
NATION.
>> THAT TRAGEDY LEAVING
FAMILY, FRIENDS, AND RESIDENTS
OF NEWTOWN REALLY AT A LOSS
FOR WORDS RIGHT NOW.
HUNDREDS LAST NIGHT TURNING UP
TO REMEMBER THOSE INNOCENT
LIVES THAT WERE TAKEN JUST IN
AN INSTANT.
♪ COME FOLLOW ME
♪ FOR I WILL BRING YOU REST.
>> THAT SERVICE LAST NIGHT AT
SAINT ROSE OF LIMA ROMAN
CATHOLIC CHURCH FILLING TO
CAPACITY.
HUNDREDS SITTING IN THE PEWS
LINING THE WALLS AND HUDDLING
NEAR THE WINDOWS OUTSIDE TO
HONOR THE SCHOOL FACULTY AND
THOSE CHILDREN WHO WERE KILLED
YESTERDAY.
26 CANDLES BURNING BRIGHT ON
THE ALTAR.
ONE FOR EACH OF THE VICTIMS.
>> IT'S WONDERFUL TO HEAR
THESE PARENTS TALK ABOUT THEIR
CHILDREN TODAY.
FATHER TALKING ABOUT THE FIRST
GOAL HIS SON GOT AND HOW
EXCITED HE WAS.
THERE WAS A LOT OF HAPPINESS
IN THE MIDST OF THE TEARS DOWN
THERE TODAY.
THEY LOVED THESE CHILDREN.
WHAT'S NOT TO LOVE.
THEY WERE SO INNOCENT AND SO
GOOD AND LOVING THEMSELVES
THERE ARE A LOT BRIGHTER STARS
OUT THERE TONIGHT BECAUSE OF
THESE KIDS.
>> PETER DOOCY IS LIVE NEWTOWN
WITH LATEST ON THESE VICTIMS.
SO TO HEAR THE WORDS OF THE
PRIEST RIGHT THERE.
>> IT IS DIFFICULT.
GOOD MORNING.
IT'S ALSO DIFFICULT TO KNOW
THAT THE MEDICAL EXAMINER'S
OFFICE HAS BEEN WORKING
THROUGHOUT THE NIGHT.
THEY ARE TRYING TO HAVE ALL
THE VICTIMS OF THIS TRAGEDY
POSITIVELY IDENTIFIED BY
TODAY.
WE'RE TOLD THAT PARENTS START
WANTED BEING BROUGHT HERE LAST
NIGHT AFTER POLICE HAD
FINISHED THEIR INVESTIGATION
TO POSITIVELY IDENTIFY THEIR
CHILDREN BUT WE STILL DON'T
KNOW THE IDENTITIES OF ANY OF
THE YOUNG VICTIMS.
WE DO KNOW THOUGH THEY WERE
ALL AGED 5 TO 10.
ONE NAME WE DO KNOW WHO WAS A
PERSON WHO LOST THEIR LIFE
YESTERDAY PRINCIPAL DAWN
HOFFSPRUNG SHE DIED FROM WHAT
WE HAVE HEARD HEROICALLY
TRYING TO STOP LANZA THE
20-YEAR-OLD WHO SHOT HIS
MOTHER BEFORE SHOWING UP AT
THINKS SCHOOL AND KILLING SIX
ADULTS AND 20 CHILDREN WITH AT
LEAST TWO PISTOLS, A GLOCK AND
A SIG SORROW.
SOWER.
>> THE INDIVIDUAL I HEAR ON
THE PHONE IS CONTINUING TO
HEAR WHAT I BELIEVES TO BE
GUNFIRE.
>> UNITS IN THE SCHOOL.
I HAVE GOT BODIES HERE.
>> TOUGH TO LISTEN TO.
MANY STUDENTS HEARD SCREAMS
THROUGH THE INTERCOM BEFORE
THEY WERE EVACUATED TO A
NEARBY FIREHOUSE.
THAT FIREHOUSE IS WHERE MANY
PARENTS WERE INSTRUCTED JUST
TO SHOW UP TO FIND OUT IF
THEIR CHILD HAD SURVIVED AT
ALL.
AND LAST NIGHT AT A CHURCH
VIGIL IN THE TINY DOWNTOWN
AREA DOWN THE ROAD, A LOT OF
THOSE PARENTS DESCRIBED HOW
HARD IT WAS NOT KNOWING IT'S
INDESCRIBABLE FOR A HALF HOUR,
45 MINUTES TO WAIT IF MY KIDS
WERE OKAY.
>> I ASKED WHAT GRADE IS SHE
BECAUSE IT BLANK OUT OF MY
MIND.
I COULDN'T EVEN THINK ABOUT IT
AND THEN WHEN I TURNED IT ON I
REALIZED SHE WAS STANDING
RIGHT NEXT TO ME.
>> WHAT WAS THAT MOMENT LIKE.
>> IT WAS A BIG RELIEF.
I WAS SHAKEN UP.
[INAUDIBLE] AT THE TIME.
>> WE HAVE BEEN TOLD THAT OUT
OF EVERYONE WHO WAS SHOT THERE
WAS JUST A SINGLE SURVIVOR.
WE DON'T KNOW WHO IT WAS BUT
WE ARE TOLD IT WAS AN ADULT
FEMALE.
WE ARE EXPECTING TO GET SOME
MORE INFORMATION FROM THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE HERE
IN ABOUT TWO AND A HALF HOURS.
BACK TO YOU IN NEW YORK.
>> PETER DOOCY THANK YOU SO
MUCH.
THEY WILL BE HOLDING A PRESS
CONFERENCE AS YOU MENTIONED
ABOUT TWO AND A HALF HOURS
FROM NOW.
THANKS, PETER.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS
OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
>> WELL, THE EMOTION SHOWN BY
PRESIDENT OBAMA SAYS IT ALL.
THE COMMANDER AND CHIEF
REACTING AT THE WHITE HOUSE
YESTERDAY TO THE HORRIFIC NEWS
THAT A GUNMAN KILLED 20
CHILDREN AND SEVEN ADULTS
INCLUDING HIS OWN MOTHER WHO
WAS KILLED EARLIER AT HOME.
FOR MORE ON THE REACTION.
WE GO TO JAMES ROSEN IN
WASHINGTON.
GOOD MORNING, JAMES.
>> PATTI ANN AND HEATHER.
GOOD MORNING AGAIN TO YOU.
PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS PLAYED THE
DIFFICULT ROLE OF CONSOLER AND
CHIEF BEFORE MOST NOTABLY
AFTER THE TUCSON, ARIZONA
MASSACRE THAT WOUNDED
CONGRESSWOMAN GABRIEL
GIFFORDS, EACH TIME ONE OF
THESE INCIDENTS HAPPENS HE
REACTS NOT AS A PRESIDENT BUT
AS A PARENT.
FLAGS WERE LOWERED TO
HALF-STAFF AT THE WHITE HOUSE
AND AT THE CAPITOL BUILDING
YESTERDAY.
POLITICIANSS FROM ALL PARTS OF
THE COUNTRY AND OBVIOUSLY BOTH
PARTIES ISSUED STATEMENTS
CONDEMNING THE SHOOTINGS,
ALTHOUGH SOME TOOK THE
OPPORTUNITY TO PRESS THE
ARGUMENT FOR MORE RESTRICTIVE
GUN LAWS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA STRUGGLED TO
HOLD BACK THOSE TEARS IN THE
JAMES S. BRADY PRESS BRIEFING
ROOM YESTERDAY.
A ROOM NAMED AFTER THE WHITE
HOUSE PRESS SECRETARY WHO WAS
SHOT AND PERMANENTLY DISABLED
IN THE ASSASSINATION ATTEMPT
ON P.M. PRESIDENT REAGAN THREE
DECADES AGO.
>> AS A COUNTRY, WE HAVE BEEN
THROUGH THIS TOO MANY TIMES,
WHETHER IT'S AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN NEWTON OR A SHOPPING
MALL IN OREGON OR A TEMPLE IN
WISCONSIN OR A MOVIE THEATER
IN AURORA OR A STREET CORNER
IN CHICAGO, THESE
NEIGHBORHOODS ARE OUR
NEIGHBORHOODS AND THESE
CHILDREN ARE OUR CHILDREN.
AND WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO
COME TOGETHER AND TAKE
MEANINGFUL ACTION TO PREVENT
MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS
IRREGARDLESS OF THE POLITICS.
>> EXACTLY WHAT THAT
MEANINGFUL ACTION MIGHT BE THE
PRESIDENT DID NOT SAY.
HE DID ADD THOUGH THAT WHILE
NOTHING CAN FILL THE SPACE OF
A LOST CHILD OR LOVED ONES,
ALL OF US CAN EXTEND A HAND TO
THOSE IN NEED.
PATTIE ANN AND HEATHER.
>> JAMES ROSEN, THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> CERTAINLY HARD FOR ANY
PARENT OUT THERE TO IMAGINE
WHAT THE FATHERS AND THE
MOTHERS OF THE VICTIMS OF
CONNECTICUT ARE GOING THROUGH
RIGHT NOW.
BUT OUR NEXT GUEST UNDERSTANDS
OUR PAIN ALL TOO WELL.
>> BETH IS HER NAME.
HER DAUGHTER RACHEL JOY SCOTT
DIED IN THE COLUMBINE
SHOOTING.
HER SON CRAIG WITNESSED THAT
TRAGEDY AND MANAGED TO
SURVIVOR.
GOOD MORNING THEIR, BETH.
I KNOW THE COLUMBINE SHOOTING
WAS 13 YEARS AGO BUT I IMAGINE
THIS BRINGS UP A WHOLE LOT OF
EMOTIONS FOR YOUR FAMILY.
>> OH, IT DID.
YESTERDAY WAS LIKE RELIVING
APRIL 20TH, 99 ALL OVER AGAIN.
SO MUCH PAIN WITH YOU MY FIRST
REACTION WAS I WAS ANGRY.
I WAS VERY ANGRY THAT THIS
WOULD HAPPEN AGAIN, ESPECIALLY
TO LITTLE CHILDREN, LITTLE
BABIES.
AND JUST ANGRY THAT THAT
SOMEONE WOULD TAKE OUT THEIR
FRUSTRATION AND THEIR ANGER
AND THEIR PAIN ON SOMEONE SO
INNOCENT.
>> AND YOU WOULD THINK THAT WE
WOULD HAVE LEARNED THE SIGNS
BY NOW TO LOOK OUT FOR IN
TROUBLED YOUNG MEN AND WOMEN
AND SADLY AT LEAST IT APPEARS
THAT THAT IS NOT THE CASE.
>> I HEARD THE FAMILY OF
ANOTHER COLUMBINE FAMILY SAY
THIS JUST YESTERDAY.
THAT WAS THAT THE REALLY
DIFFICULT PHASE ACTUALLY
BEGINS FOR THOSE FAMILIES
RIGHT NOW.
COULD YOU TALK TO US A LITTLE
BIT ABOUT THAT?
>> SURE.
IT'S SO UNREAL WHAT THEY ARE
EXPERIENCING NOW IS SO UNREAL.
IT'S LIKE BEING HIT BY A
FREIGHT TRAIN BUT YOU'RE
LIVING WITH THE PAIN AND THE
LOSS AND THE GRIEF.
AND YOU ARE JUST NUMB INSIDE.
SO IT COMES AND GOES.
THE WEEPING, THE DISBELIEF,
THE DENIAL, ALL OF THOSE
THINGS ARE SO IN YOUR FACE AT
THIS POINT IN TIME.
THERE IS IS NO WAY TO ESCAPE
IT THERE IS NO PLACE TO GO TO
HIDE.
AND I REMEMBER FEELING LIKE I
JUST WANTED TO DIE.
I COULDN'T BREATHE.
I MEAN THERE WERE TIMES WHERE
I FELT LIKE I COULDN'T
BREATHE.
>> BETH, HOW ABOUT YOUR SON?
YOUR SON MANAGED TO SURVIVE
THAT DAY.
HOW DID YOU HELP HIM GET
THROUGH IT.
>> CRAIG WAS IN BAD SHAPE FOR
ALMOST TWO YEARS.
AND I QUIT MY FULL-TIME JOB
AND WORKED AT HOME AND TOOK
CARE OF HIM.
HE BECAME MY PRIORITY.
I WAS AFRAID I WAS GOING TO
HAVE TWO COLUMBINE VICTIMS
BECAUSE I DIDN'T WANT TO HAVE
AN EMOTIONAL CRIPPLE AND HE
WASN'T PHYSICALLY DAMAGED BUT
WHAT HE WITNESSED WAS TWO
FRIENDS DYING AND SEEING
EVERYTHING AND THE CARNAGE OF
THAT LIBRARY WHERE 10 CHILDREN
PERISHED THAT DAY WAS TOO MUCH
FOR HIM.
SO IT TOOK HIM ALMOST TWO
YEARS TO BECOME, YOU KNOW,
HIMSELF AGAIN.
>> CERTAINLY AFFECTING YOUR
SON, YOUR ENTIRE FAMILY AND SO
MANY THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE FOR
THEIR LIFETIME.
BUT I'M HAPPY TO TELL FOLKS
THAT YOU SAY THAT YOU DID FIND
HAPPINESS AGAIN.
IT TOOK A LONG TIME BUT YOU
WERE ABLE TO FIND THAT
HAPPINESS.
BETH, THANK YOU SO MUCH, SORRY
AGAIN FOR THE LOSS OF YOUR
DAUGHTER IN THAT SHOOTING.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU, HEATHER.
>> PATTI ANN.
>> MANY PARENTS ARE NOW AT
HOME ASKING THEMSELVES COULD
THIS HAPPEN AT MY CHILD'S
SCHOOL?
SO WHAT CAN SCHOOLS DO TO
PROTECT CHILDREN?
LET'S TALK NOW WITH A FORMER
DETECTIVE AND NEW JERSEY
POLICE COMMISSIONER STEPHAN
WRONGERS.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR JOINING
US.
>> GOOD MORNING.
>> PRIVATE SECURITY FIRMS SAY
THEY ARE ALREADY FIELDING
.ALLS FROM SCHOOLS IN THE WAKE
WHAT TYPE OF SECURITY IS
APPROPRIATE AT A SCHOOL?
>> LET ME SHARE THIS WITH YOU
THAT POLICE AND TEACHERS
AROUND THIS NATION ARE TRAINED
FOR INCIDENTS LIKE THIS.
ALTHOUGH I HAVE TO ADMIT TO
YOUNER HAVE ANY ONE OF US IN
LAW ENFORCEMENT OR TEACHERS
ACROSSED THE COUNTRY BELIEVED
WE WOULD BE FACING SOMETHING
LIKE THIS.
SCHOOLS ACROSS THE DISTRICT
ARE, IN FACT, DOING THE BEST
THEY COULD.
THEY PUT CAMERAS UP.
THEY PUT METAL DETECTORS UP.
THEY DO EVERYTHING THEY CAN TO
PREVENT INCIDENTS LIKE THIS.
THE BOTTOM LINE REGARDING THIS
INCIDENT AS REPORTS COME OUT
IT LOOKS LIKE YOU WERE UNABLE
TO PREVENT SOMETHING LIKE
THIS.
THE GUY HAD THESE GUNS.
I UNDERSTAND HE SHOT HIS WAY
THROUGH THE DOOR.
YOU CAN DO EVERYTHING POSSIBLE
TO PREVENT SOMETHING LIKE THIS
FROM HAPPENING, BUT SOMETIMES
YOU CAN'T DO VERY MUCH AS IN A
CASE LIKE THIS.
>> THIS SCHOOL HAD A BUZZER.
AT FIRST THEY WERE SPECULATING
THAT HE WAS BUZZED IN BECAUSE
HE IS KNOWN TO THE SCHOOL.
HIS MOTHER WORKS THERE AS A
SUBSTITUTE TEACHER.
SOMETHING LIKE A.
[ BUZZER BUZZER
INEFFECTIVE.
SOMEBODY BUZZES THEY LET THEM
ON IN.
THAT'S NOT ENOUGH.
BUT PEOPLE DON'T WANT TO TURN
THE SCHOOL INTO AN ARMED
PRISON ALMOST BY HAVING METAL
DETECTORS AND SECURITY GUARDS.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU KNOW, I'VE BEEN TO SCHOOL
DISTRICTS WHERE NOW HERE I'M
AN ELECTED OFFICIAL IN NUTTILY
AND EVEN IN OUR HIGH SCHOOL
WHEN I WALK IN I'M GREETED BY
AN INDIVIDUAL.
THEY TAKE ME TO THE OFFICE.
I SIGN IN.
SO EVERYONE WHO WALKS IN THAT
BUILDING IS CHECKED OUT.
NOW, YOU ARE RIGHT.
DO YOU WANT YOUR SCHOOLS TO BE
ARMED CAMPS?
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
BUT I THINK WHAT WE HAVE TO
FOCUS ON IN THIS CASE AND
OTHER CASES.
THE POLICE AND THE TEACHERS
DID EVERYTHING THEY COULD TO
PREVENT MORE TRAGEDY.
THEY DID A SUBURB JOB.
MOVING FORWARD WE HAVE TO
BELIEVE WE DID THE BEST THICK
WE DID IN THIS CASE AND
HOPEFULLY AS TIME GOES ON WE
CAN ASSESS EACH INCIDENT AND
MAYBE STRENGTHEN OUR SECURITY
IN CERTAIN AREAS.
AGAIN, YOU CAN ONLY DO SO
MUCH.
AND AS YOU SAID THROUGH THE
THIS BROADCAST OUR HEART GOES
OUT TO EVERYONE HERE STEVE
ROGERS DETECTIVE AND POLICE
COMMISSIONER THANK YOU.
>> YOU'RE WELCOME.
>> WE'LL BE BACK WITH MUCH
MORE ON THE CONNECTICUT
TRAGEDY.
SO MANY UNANSWERED QUESTIONS.
WHAT ARE DETECTIVES LOOKING TO
LEARN FROM THE CRIME SCENE?
FORENSIC PATHOLOGIST
DR. MICHAEL BODEN JOINS US
NEXT MUCH
18 CHILDREN PRONOUNCED DEAD AT
THE SCHOOLS.
TWO PRONOUNCED DEAD AT AREA
HOSPITALS AND SIX ADULTS
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCENE
AT THE SCHOOL.
AS THE GOVERNOR HAS REPORTED,
THE SHOOTER IS DECEASED.
DECEASED IN THE SCHOOL.
>> IT IS EXPECTED TO TAKE DAYS
FOR INVESTIGATORS TO PROCESS
THE GRUESOME CRIME SCENE AT
THE SCHOOL.
FOX NEWS CONTRIBUTOR AND
FORENSIC PATHOLOGIST
DR. MICHAEL BODIEN IS HERE TO
EXPLAIN WHAT THEY ARE LOOKING
FOR AND WHAT THEY HOPE TO
LEARN FROM IT THANK YOU FOR
JOINING US, DOCTOR.
THE GUNMAN HERE IS DEAD.
>> RIGHT.
>> NOT LIKE THEY ARE BUILDING
A CASE FOR A TRIAL OR NEED
EVIDENCE TO FIGURE OUT WHAT
HAPPENED.
WE KNOW WHAT HAPPENED BUT WHAT
ARE THEY LOOKING FOR?
>> WELL, YOU ARE RIGHT.
WHY -- WE KNOW WHAT THE CAUSE
OF DEATH ARE AND WE KNOW THAT
THE SHOOTER IS DEAD.
BUT THERE MAY BE A LOT OF
CIVIL TRIALS AS TO PROTECTION
OF THE CHILD, AS TO PROTECTION
OF THE CHILDREN.
WHY WASN'T THIS 20-YEAR-OLD
KID PICKED UP EARLIER?
IF HE WAS GETTING MEDICATION,
COULD THE MEDICATION HELP
TRIGGER OFF MORE AGGRESSION?
THERE WILL BE CIVIL LAWSUITS
AND THERE MAY BE SOMEBODY WHO
IS CONNECTED TO THIS WHO WILL
ALSO BE CHARGED CRIMINALLY IF
THERE WAS SOMEBODY ELSE WHO
WORKED WITH ADAM.
AND THAT'S ONE OF THE THINGS
THE POLICE ARE LOOKING INTO.
WHAT'S HAPPENING NOW IS THAT
THEY ARE ASSESSING ALL OF THE
FORENSIC EVIDENCE AT THE
SCENE, TAKING PICTURES OF
EVERYBODY, -- WORK AT THE
SCENE BUT THEN THEY WILL WORK
AT THE MEDICAL EXAMINER'S
OFFICE AND DOCUMENT EVERY
INJURY AND PERHAPS DO
AUTOPSIES ON THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN BECAUSE ALL THE
BULLETS HAVE TO BE REMOVED.
ALL THE BULLETS WILL THEN BE
CHECKED WITH THE TWO WEAPONS
THAT YOU MENTIONED AND TO MAKE
SURE THERE ISN'T A THIRD
WEAPON, YOU KNOW, THAT WAS
DISCHARGED.
>> APPARENTLY THERE WAS A
THIRD WEAPON IN THE CAR FROM
WHAT WE ARE HEARING NOW
ALTHOUGH AGAIN AS YOU SAY SO
MANY QUESTIONS.
>> THERE WERE RUMORS OF TWO
SHOOTERS WHICH PROBABLY
DOESN'T EXIST.
>> RIGHT.
>> BUT THEY HAVE TO MAKE SURE
THAT SOMEBODY ELSE WASN'T
DISCHARGING A WEAPON.
>> YEAH.
SO PEOPLE ARE SHOKDZ AT THE
DEATH TOLL HERE.
9/11 A MASS SHOOTING LIKE
THIS, YOU OFTEN HAVE MANY MORE
INJURIES.
NOT EVERYONE DIED.
SOME PEOPLE SURVIVED.
WHAT HAPPENED HERE?
>> THAT'S VERY INTERESTING
BECAUSE THIS SHOOTER MUST HAVE
GONE TO EACH CHILD AND MADE
SURE THAT THERE WAS A SHOOTING
OF A VITAL ORGAN IN THE HEAD.
INFORMATION THAT THEY WERE
DEAD.
YOU ARE RIGHT.
USUALLY THERE ARE SOME PEOPLE
WHO SURVIVE.
INJURED BUT SURVIVED.
HE MUST HAVE GONE AROUND TO
EACH CHILD.
AND ALL WITHIN A COUPLE
MINUTES.
THAT'S PART OF THE PROBLEM.
THESE WEAPONS CAN BE
DISCHARGED VERY QUICKLY.
AND HE HAD TO RELOAD.
THOSE GUNS ONLY WOULD NORMALLY
HOLD ONLY 12, UP TO 15
BULLETS.
SO HE WOULD HAVE -- THEY SAID
THERE WERE 100 BULLETS FIRED.
WE DON'T KNOW THAT YET.
THEY ARE FINDING THAT OUT.
HE MAY HAVE HAD TO RELOAD ONE
OR TWO TIMES.
>> JUST A HORRIFIC STORY.
>> AND JUST THE HELPLESSNESS.
I I AGREE VERY MUCH WITH YOUR
PREVIOUS GUEST.
WHO SAID NO MATTER HOW GOOD WE
ARE IF SOMEBODY BURSTS IN AND
SHOOTS A LOT OF PEOPLE AND
KILLS HIMSELF BY THE TIME HELP
ARRIVES, IT'S ALL OVER.
>> DR. MICHAEL BADEN, THANK
YOU SO MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
>> WHEN WE COME BACK, A SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST WILL TALK TO US
ABOUT THE LONG-TERM EFFECT
THIS WILL HAVE ON THE CHILDREN
WHO SURVIVED THE MASSACRE.
>> THERE WAS NOISE, THEY WERE
KIND OF HUDDLED UP, THEY WERE
EVACUATED.
I THINK, YOU KNOW, PROBABLY
THE SCARIER PART FOR THEM WAS
BEING TAKEN OUT OF A ROOM BY
POLICE OFFICERS AND, YOU KNOW,
THAT KIND OF THING, WITHDRAWN
GUNS.
I THINK THAT WAS PROBABLY THE
HARROWING MOMENT FOR THEM.
AND THE PARENT REACTIONS, I
MEAN, I DON'T KNOW SOME KIDS
OBVIOUSLY SAW MORE AND
THEREFORE THEY WERE MORE
IMPACTED.
>> CERTAINLY MANY OF US WILL
NEVER FORGET THE DETAILS OF
THAT TRAGEDY.
YOUNG STUDENTS WHO WERE THERE
AND MANAGED TO SURVIVE A LOT
OF US ARE ASKING NOW WHAT WILL
THEY REMEMBER AND HOW WILL
THOSE CHILDREN PROCESS IT?
WE ARE JOINED BY DR. THOMAS
KIRSTEN A SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST
IN NEW JERSEY WHAT ARE THEY
FACING LONG-TERM.
>> ONE THING WE WILL SEE IS
POST-TRAUMATIC STRESS DISORDER
NO DOUBT ABOUT IT.
>> EVEN A A-YEAR-OLD.
>> DEFINITELY, WITHOUT
QUESTION.
THIS IS IS TRAUMATIC LIFE
INCIDENT THEY WILL CARRY NO
DIFFERENT FROM A WAR VETERAN
IN VIETNAM WHO IS HITTING THE
DECK 20 YEARS LATER WHEN HE
HEARS A HELICOPTER GO BY.
>> SOMETHING CAN BE BROUGHT UP
20 YEARS FROM NOW.
>> TRIGGER.
PART OF PTSD.
TRIGGER DEFENSE MECHANISM IN
THE BODY.
AND, YOU KNOW, THE PROBLEM IS
THESE KIDS ARE REALLY GOING TO
NEED SOME -- THE KIDS THAT
WERE EXPOSED TO THIS INCIDENT
ARE GOING TO NEED SOME
LONG-TERM INTENSE
PSYCHOTHERAPY.
>> EVERY SINGLE CHILD
PROBABLY.
>> YES, DEFINITELY, NO
QUESTION.
>> HOW DO YOU BEGIN TO TREAT
SOMETHING LIKE.
THIS WHAT'S GOING TO HAVE TO
HAPPEN ARE THE SCHOOLS.
THEY ARE WORKING ON IT NOW.
COME UP WITH PLAN.
I WORK AT A HIGH SCHOOL IN NEW
JERSEY AS WELL AS PRIVATE
PRACTICE AND IN SITUATIONS
LIKE THIS WE HAVE THE FLIGHT
TEAM.
A DIFFERENT COMMUNITY
ORGANIZATIONS THAT PROVIDE
COUNSELING SERVICES AS WELL AS
OTHER SCHOOLS WILL MOST LIKELY
STEP IN AND PROVIDE FREE
SERVICES.
PROBABLY HAVE ON SITE
COUNSELING AT THE SCHOOL WHEN
KIDS RETURN TO SCHOOL.
>> THIS IS SOMETHING THAT'S
PROBABLY NEEDED A LOT MORE
THAN JUST A FEW SESSIONS.
>> NO DOUBT.
>> TALKING YEARS AND YEARS.
>> YES.
>> IT DEPENDS ON THE NATURE OF
THE KID, THE PERSONALITY OF
THE INDIVIDUAL, TEACHERS ARE
GOING TO NEED ASSISTANCE.
ADMINISTRATORS.
>> HOW DO YOU KNOW IF YOUR
CHILD IS DOING OKAY?
>> LOOK FOR THE WARNING SIGNS.
WE ALL KNOW OUR KIDS IF YOU
HAVE CHILDREN.
YOU KNOW THEIR PERSONALITY.
YOU KNOW THEIR TRAITS.
IF YOU SEE THINGS THAT ARE OFF
MARK FOR THEM.
>> WE'RE NOT TALKING ABOUT
MOODY TEENAGERS HERE.
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT VERY
YOUNG CHILDREN THAT RESPOND
DIFFERENTLY.
>> THESE KIDS ARE GOING TO
WANT TO BE SLEEPING IN BED
WITH THEIR PARENTS.
I'M SURE THE PARENTS ARE GOING
TO WANT THEM SLEEPING IN THE
BED WITH ELM.
THIS THAT BREAKS THE RULES A
LITTLE BIT.
IN A CASE LIKE THIS I THINK
IT'S NECESSARY TO HAVE A
SECURE TIGHT FAMILY BOND FOR
THESE FAMILIES IN CONNECTICUT.
>> HOW DO YOU FEEL ABOUT ALL
THESE CHILDREN BEING
INTERVIEWED ON TELEVISION THE
PARENTS LETTING THEM DO THAT
AND MEDIA ORGANIZATION.
>> THE PARENTS ARE SO SHELL
SHOCKED THEY MAY NOT
NECESSARILY KNOW WHAT THEY ARE
DOING RIGHT NOW.
I DON'T KNOW THAT I AGREE WITH
IT MAYBE FOR SOME OF THEM THEY
FEEL -- I FEEL I NEED TO BE
HERE TODAY BECAUSE IT IS
SOMETHING THAT HITS HOME TO ME
AS A FATHER OF I DON'T OUTCOME
KIDS.
THAN THEY FEEL THIS NEED TO
BROADCAST THEIR MESSAGE TO THE
WORLD.
>> HARD TO SEE.
IT'S HARD FOR ME AS A PARENT.
>> SAME WITH ME, VERY
DIFFICULT.
>> WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THOSE
WATCHING OUR PROGRAM THIS
MORNING THAT WEREN'T DIRECTLY
AFFECTED BY THIS THAT HAVE
CHILDREN IN THE HOME AND WILL
NATURALLY HEAR ABOUT THIS.
>> WHAT I WANT TO SAY TO
EVERYBODY IS TAKE THE WEEKEND.
REALLY EMBRACE YOUR KIDS.
DON'T TAKE THEM FOR GRANTED.
AT THE SAME TIME YOU DON'T
WANT TO BE WATCHING, IF YOU
HAVE YOUNG KIDS, YOU DENT WANT
TO HAVE BEEN HAVING YOUR TV
BROADCAST.
THEY ARE HEARING ALL OF THIS
STUFF.
WE DON'T WANT TO INSTILL
UNNECESSARY FEAR AND ANXIETY
AMONG YOUNG KIDS.
>> YOUNG CHILDREN WILL PICK
THAT UP?
>> NO DOUBT ABOUT IT.
>> QUICKLY, WHAT DO YOU SAY
ABOUT THIS TO CHILDREN?
DO YOU SAY THERE IS EVIL IN
THE WORLD.
>> IT DEPENDS ON YOUR KIDS.
I'M NOT GOING TO BRING IT IT
UP TO MY OWN KIDS.
OTHER PEOPLE WANT TO BE
PROACTIVE.
IF I SEE LITTLE THINGS
HAPPENING WITH MY KIDS I WILL
TALK TO THEM ABOUT IT MY
APPROACH IS I WANT TO INSULATE
THEM FROM THIS.
I DON'T WANT THEM TO BE AFRAID
OF GOING TO SCHOOL EVERY DAY.
>> CERTAINLY.
DOCTOR, THANK YOU FOR COMING
IN THIS MORNING.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> WE'LL BE BACK IN JUST A FEW
MINUTES.
I HAD ENOUGH OF FEELING
EMBARRASSED ABOUT MY SKIN.
[ Designer ]
ENOUGH OF JUST COVERING UP
MY MODERATE TO SEVERE
PLAQUE PSORIASIS.
I DECIDED ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
♪
[ Spa Lady ]
I STARTED ENBREL.
IT'S CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO PROVIDE CLEARER SKIN.
[ RV Guy ] ENBREL MAY NOT WORK
FOR EVERYONE --
AND MAY NOT CLEAR YOU
COMPLETELY,
BUT FOR MANY, IT GETS SKIN
CLEARER FAST, WITHIN 2 MONTHS,
AND KEEPS IT CLEARER
UP TO 9 MONTHS.
[ Male Announcer ]
BECAUSE ENBREL®, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL,
EVENTS INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS, LYMPHOMA,
OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING ENBREL,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START ENBREL IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON ENBREL, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING,
OR PALENESS.
IF YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH, ASK
YOUR DERMATOLOGIST ABOUT ENBREL.