>>> MAKE SURE TO TUNE IN TO FOX
NEWS TONIGHT AT 6:00 P.M.
BRET BAIER WILL BRING YOU
COVERAGE OF THE PRESIDENT'S
RIFLE ARRIVAL AT NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> ED HENRY IS TRAVELING WITH
THE PRESIDENT, THE PRESIDENT'S
FOURTH VISIT TO THE SITE OF A
MASS SHOOTING.
IT'S BEEN A TOUGH WEEKEND AND
WILL CONTINUE TO BE DIFFICULT.
KELLY WRIGHT, THANK YOU FOR
FILLING IN.
>> MY PLEASURE.
>> OUR PRAYERS ARE WITH ALL THE
PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>>> NO BREAK FROM THE GRIEVING.
THE NATION IS MOURNING THE
VICTIMS OF THE HORRIFIC MASS
SHOOTING IN CONNECTICUT.
PRESIDENT OBAMA PREPARING TO
ATTEND AND INTERFAITH VIGIL THIS
EVENING IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WHILE INVESTIGATORS TRY TO PIECE
TOGETHER MORE INFORMATION ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED AND WHY IN THAT
TERRIFYING SHOOTING SPREE.
AMONG THE CONFUSION AND SORROW
ARE STORIES OF HEROSIM LIKE
VICTORIA SOTO, WHO REPORTEDLY
USED HER OWN BODY TO SHIELD HER
FIRST GRADERS FROM GUNFIRE.
HER HOMETOWN CELEBRATED HER LIFE
AND SELFLESS ACT OF LOVE AND
DEVOTION TO HER BELOVED
STUDENTS.
>> I JUST HOPE THAT ONE DAY
HE'LL KNOW SHE'S IN A BETTER
PLACE AND DIED A HERO.
>> THE PAIN, HOW THOSE MOTHERS
MUST BE FEELING AT THIS TIME,
BECAUSE THIS IS MY ONLY CHILD.
I COULDN'T PICTURE THAT.
THAT'S WHY I'M HERE TODAY,
BECAUSE SHE SAVED A LOT OF KIDS'
LIVES.
>> IT'S FOR SO MANY,
UNIMAGINABLE.
VICTORIA SOTO WAS ONE OF THE 26
PEOPLE KILLED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY FRIDAY.
ACCORDING TO POLICE, OF THE 20
CHILDREN ATTACKED AND KILLED,
EIGHT WERE BOYS, 12 WERE GIRLS.
ALL SIX ADULT VICTIMS WERE
WOMEN.
GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE, ALTHOUGH
IT'S NOT.
ESPECIALLY IN CONNECTICUT.
I'M JAMIE COLBY, WELCOME TO A
BRAND-NEW HOUR.
>> I'M ERIC SHAWN.
WE'RE TRYING TO COME TO TERMS
WITH THE INCOMPREHENSIBLE.
WHY THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER WOULD
DO THIS AND WHAT PROMPTED HIM TO
TARGET THE INNOCENT.
WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT ADAM
LANZA AS WELL AS DETAILS ABOUT
HIS FAMILY AND WHAT MIGHT HAVE
TRIGGERED THIS HORRENDOUS
RAMPAGE.
PETER DOOCY IS LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT WITH THE VERY
LATEST.
HELLO, PETER.
>> ERIC, I SPOKE TO ONE OF ADAM
LANZA'S CLASSMATES WHO TOLD ME
ADAM WAS SHY AND THE TYPE OF KID
YOU COULD SAY HI TO IN THE HALL
AND HE WOULD SAY HI BACK BUT
THAT WAS ALL THE TALKING HE
WOULD DO.
FEDERAL INVESTIGATORS WILL COME
HERE TODAY VISIT GUN STORES AND
SHOOTING RANGES, SEARCHING FOR A
HINT ABOUT WHAT LED TO THIS MASS
MURDER THAT TOOK THE LIVES OF 26
PEOPLE INSIDE AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, INCLUDING 30-YEAR-OLD
LAUREN ROUSSEAU WHO GOT THE
PERMANENT SUBSTITUTED TEACHING
JOB SHE STRIVED FOR.
16 VICTIMS WERE BORN IN 1996,
FOUR IN 1995 AND EVERY DETAIL
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED ON FRIDAY
SEEMS TO BE HARDER WHO HEAR THAN
THE LAST.
>> THERE WERE IN CUTE KID STUFF.
THEY'RE FIRST GRADERS WEARING
CUTE KID STUFF, YOU KNOW.
IT'S THE KIND OF STUFF YOU WOULD
SEND YOUR KIDS OR YOUR ARE
GRANDKIDS OUT THE DOOR TO FIRST
GRADE IN.
>> FLOWERS AND CANDLES AND
VIGILS POPPED UP ALL OVER
NEWTOWN.
NEIGHBORS WANT TO KNOW HOW THIS
HAPPENED.
THE AUNT SAYS THE REASON SO MANY
GUNS WERE IN ADAM LANZA'S HOME
WAS SELF-DEFENSE.
>> SELF-DEFENSE.
NO OTHER REASON.
THEY WERE NOT A VIOLENT FAMILY.
THEY WERE NOT ONES TO -- SHE HAD
IT, IT WAS HAVE BEEN FOR
SELF-DEFENSE BECAUSE SHE DID
LIVE ALONE.
>> THE NATIONAL SUPPORT FOR THE
VICTIMS OF THIS TRAGEDY HAS BEEN
IMMENSE.
JUST THIS MORNING, AN ANONYMOUS
PERSON FROM NORTH CAROLINA
DONATED 26 CHRISTMAS TREES SET
UP RIGHT NOW ON DICKINSON DRIVE,
THE DRIVE TO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
LOCALLY JUST A STREET AWAY FROM
HERE, YESTERDAY WE CAME ACROSS A
GARAGE SALE THAT WAS BEING RUN
BY TWO STUDENTS WHO WERE INSIDE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY WHEN THE
SHOOTING STARTED.
THEY GOT OUT AND WERE SELLING
THEIR TOYS TO RAISE MONEY FOR
THE VICTIMS' FAMILIES.
BACK TO YOU.
>> PETER, SUCH HEARTBREAKING
STORIES THAT HAVE DEEPLY TOUCHED
OUR NATION THIS WEEKEND.
THANK YOU, PETER.
>>> THE COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT IS STRUGGLING TO
COME TO GRIPS.
RESIDENTS HOLDING A VIGIL LAST
NIGHT FOR THOSE WHO WERE LOST.
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS EXPECTED TO
ATTEND ANOTHER PLANNED ONE FOR
THIS EVENING.
FOR NOW, FOLKS IN THE COMMUNITY
ARE TRYING TO BE THERE FOR EACH
OTHER IN THIS HOUR OF NEED.
>> WE JUST GOT IN FROM
WASHINGTON, D.C. AND I SAW WHAT
WAS HAPPENING.
I JUST -- WE HAD TO GET BACK AS
SOON AS WE COULD.
WE HAVE TOO MANY CONNECTIONS AND
TOO MANY PEOPLE HERE WE KNOW
THAT ARE INVOLVED.
I PRAY GOD WILL HEAL THESE
PEOPLE WHO LOST CHILDREN.
WE HAVE TWO YOUNG DAUGHTERS AND
I JUST CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT IT
MUST FEEL LIKE.
>> A TOWN SMALL ENOUGH WHERE
NEIGHBORS ARE FEELING THE PAIN
EVEN IF THEY'RE NOT IMMEDIATELY
AFFECTED.
ANNA IS LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT WITH THE COMMUNITY
RESPONSE.
HOW ARE THEY DOING TODAY?
>> Reporter: THEY'RE
STRUGGLING.
DURING IT TIME OF DESPAIR,
RESIDENTS ARE STRUGGLING TO MAKE
SENSE OF THIS TRAGEDY AND
REMEMBER THERE'S STILL GOOD IN
THE WORLD.
CHURCH SERVICES LIKE THE ONE
BEHIND ME ARE BECOMING MEMORIAL
SERVICES HONORING 20 INNOCENT
CHILDREN AND 6 ADULTS WHO LOST
THEIR LIVES.
MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS ARE POPPING
UP ALL OVER, MANY READING PRAY
FOR SANDY HOOK.
YOUNG CHILDREN WHO HAD SO MUCH
TO LOOK FORWARD TO ARE
REMEMBERED ON THIS SUNDAY
MORNING.
EMILIE PARKER, HER HEARTWARMING
SMILE, ONE OF THE MANY THINGS
HER FATHER WILL MISS.
>> I'VE BEEN TEACHING HER
PORTUGUESE SO OUR LAST
CONVERSATION WAS IN PORTUGUESE.
AND SHE TOLD ME GOOD MORNING AND
ASKED HOW I WAS DOING.
I SAID I WAS DOING WELL.
SHE SAID THEY LOVED ME AND I
GAVE HER A KISS AND I WAS OUT
THE DOOR.
>> KIDS THAT SURVIVED THE
MASSACRE LOST MANY OF THEIR
PLAYMATES AND SOME OF THEIR
FAVORITE TEACHERS.
THIRD GRADER MALIA ALI CARRIED A
POSTER PAYING TRIBUTE TO
VICTORIA SOTO.
>> SHE WAS A REALLY GOOD
TEACHER.
MY FAVORITE FIRST GRADE TEACHER.
>> LAST NIGHT HUNDREDS GATHERED
FOR WHAT IS NORMALLY A SATURDAY
NIGHT CHILDREN'S SERVICE AT
ST. ROSE OF LIMA CHURCH.
SOME OF THE PARENTS WHO LOST
THEIR CHILDREN MOURNING WITH
NEIGHBORS DURING THE STANDING
ROOM ONLY SERVICE THAT SPILLED
OUT IN THE SANCTUARY.
PARENTS ARE TAKING A BREAK FROM
PLANNING FUNERALS FOR THEIR
LITTLE ONES.
PRESIDENT BARACK OBAMA IS
PLANNING ON VISITING SANDY HOOK
LATER TODAY, THE FOURTH TIME
HE'S VISITED A TOWN MOURNING
FOLLOWING A MASS SHOOTING.
>> ANN IN A, THANK YOU.
>>> I WANT TO REMIND EVERYBODY
WHEN PRESIDENT OBAMA DOES ARRIVE
IN NEWTOWN, WE WILL HAVE LIVE
COVERAGE OF THAT INTERFAITH
VIGIL.
BRET BAIER WILL ANCHOR THAT AT
6:00 P.M. EASTERN HERE ON "FOX
NEWS CHANNEL."
>> WHILE THE NATION HAS BEEN
FOCUSED ON THE TRAGIC EVENTS IN
CONNECTICUT, POLICE AND SCHOOL
OFFICIALS IN OKLAHOMA DISRUPTED
A SCHOOL SHOOTING PLOT OF THEIR
OWN.
18-YEAR-OLD SAMMY CHAVEZ IS
BEHIND BARS, ACCUSED OF PLOTTING
TO BOMB AND SHOOT STUDENTS IN
THE AUDITORIUM OF BARTERSVILLE
HIGH SCHOOL.
LUCKILY FELLOW STUDENTS HELPED
PREVENT A POTENTIAL TRAGEDY.
>> OUR PROCESS WORKED WELL SO WE
CAN BUILD ON THAT.
WHAT WE HAVE IN PLACE, WE'RE
GOING TO CONTINUE TO USE THAT
AND HOPEFULLY WE NEVER HAVE TO
DEAL WITH A SITUATION LIKE THIS
AGAIN.
ANYTIME WE'RE CONCERNED ABOUT
THE SAFETY OF OUR STUDENTS,
THAT'S THE MOST PRIORITY.
>> SCHOOL OFFICIALS THERE ADDED
EXTRA PATROLS TO KEEP PEOPLE
SAFE FOR THE NEXT FEW WEEKS.
>>> THE SHOOTINGS ARE SPARKING
DISCUSSIONS ABOUT THE BEST WAY
TO KEEP CHILDREN SAFE AT SCHOOL.
MANY SCHOOLS AROUND THE NATION
ARE CONDUCTING STANDARD SECURITY
DRILLS AFTER THE 1999 SHOOTING
IN COLUMBINE BUT NOW SOME
OFFICIALS SAY IT MAY BE TIME TO
UPDATE THOSE PROCEDURES.
JOINING US NOW IS DR. SONY
SHEPHERD, SAFETY ANALYST AT SAFE
HAVEN INTERNATIONAL.
GREAT TO SEE YOU.
>> GOOD MORNING.
I WOULD LIKE TO SAY OUR THOUGHTS
AND PRAYERS ARE WITH THE TOWN IN
CONNECTICUT AND WE'RE JUST
HORRIFIED BY THAT TRAGEDY.
>> IT'S JUST -- YOU CAN'T EVEN
IMAGINE WHAT THOSE FAMILIES MUST
BE GOING THROUGH.
AND MAYBE WE'RE GOING A STEP TOO
FAR HERE BEING A LITTLE BIT
SELFISH IN TALKING ABOUT HOW TO
KEEP OUR OWN KIDS SAFE BUT WE
HOPE TO LEARN SOMETHING FROM
THIS.
YOU WERE VERY KIND IN SENDING ME
A WHITE PAPER TO READ ABOUT
THIS.
I FIND THIS INTERESTING, IT'S
CALLED FIGHT, FLIGHT, OR
LOCKDOWN.
ACTUALLY RECOMMENDING THAT STAFF
AND STUDENTS ARE TAUGHT HOW TO
ATTACK ACTIVE SHOOTERS.
THE TEACHERS IN THIS CASE DID
TRY TO APPROACH.
WHAT WENT RIGHT AND WHAT ELSE
CAN BE DONE?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, THE
INTERESTING THING ABOUT THE
WHITE PAPER THAT WE SENT, IT
OUTLINES THE PROS AND CONS.
THERE'S SOME SCHOOL OF THOUGHT
BY PRACTITIONERS THAT -- TO TRY
TO FIGHT AND ATTACK AN ATTACKER.
WHILE IN SOME INSTANCES THAT CAN
BE EFFECTIVE, ONE THING THAT WE
NEED TO CAUTION SCHOOLS IN DOING
THAT IS THAT YOU CAN MAKE A
SITUATION MORE HARMFUL IN A
SITUATION WHERE, FOR EXAMPLE, AN
AGGRESSOR MAY COME INTO A
CLASSROOM AND WANTING TO TAKE
HOSTAGES AND YOU FIGHT THEM.
THAT COULD TURN A HOSTAGE
SITUATION INTO A SHOOTING
SITUATION.
WE HAVE SEEN THAT IN THIS
COUNTRY.
SO THAT MAY NOT BE THE BEST
ALTERNATIVE.
>> IT HAS TO BE ANALYZED
QUICKLY.
IT'S LIFE OR DEATH AND YOU NEED
TO MAKE A SPLIT-SECOND DECISION.
CAN YOU TEACH TEACHERS -- CAN
YOU TEACH STUDENTS?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
ONE OF THE APPROACHES THAT WE
ADVOCATE OVER ANYTHING IS WHAT
WE CALL AN ALL HAZARD APPROACH.
THAT IS LOOKING AT SAFETY SAFETY
HOLISTICALLY.
WE HAVE TO TRAIN TEACHERS, YOU
HAVE TO TRAIN EDUCATORS TO DO
MENTAL SIMULATION DRILLS AND
PRACTICE RESPONSE SO THEY FEEL
COMFORT THE CARRYING OUT THEIR
FUNCTION.
ALSO ENPOWER THEM TO MAKE THE
NECESSARY LIFE-SAVING DECISIONS
WITHOUT BEING TOLD TO DO SO.
>> THEY HAVE TO DO THAT AND THEY
HAVE TO TEACH OUR CHILDREN ALSO.
IS THAT TOO MUCH RESPONSIBILITY
FOR A TEACHER?
SHOULD WE NOT LEAVE THIS TO THE
PROFESSIONALS?
HOW IT DO YOU FEEL ABOUT HAVING
A ARMED UNIFORMED OR
PLAIN-CLOTHED SECURITY
PROFESSIONAL AT THE DOOR OF
EVERY SCHOOLIE THE COUNTRY?
THERE.
>> MOST SCHOOLS HAVE CAMPUS
POLICE WHO ARE ARMED.
ONE THING WE ADVOCATE FOR
TEACHERS, YOU HAVE TO DO MONTHLY
FIRE DRILLS.
YOU HAVE TO DO MONTHLY DRILLS.
SO LET'S TAKE THOSE DRILLS AND
REVIEW THEM AND SEE WHAT WORKED
WELL.
REMEMBER, A FIRE DRILL IS AN
EVACUATION DRILL.
SO WE CAN TAKE WHAT WE'RE IT
DOING AND IMPROVE UPON THAT.
WE STRESS THAT WHEN DEVELOPING
CRISIS PLANS, SCHOOLS WORK WITH
YOUR LOCAL OFFICIALS, WITH YOUR
LAW ENFORCEMENT, WITH YOUR FIRE,
SO YOU GET LOCAL INPUT TO THE
BEST ACTION TO TAKE.
>> WITH PARENTS, TOO, NOTIFYING
THEM, WHAT THEY CAN DO AS THEY
HEAR IT, FOR MANY, ON THE NEWS.
THANK YOU, D
VERY HELPFUL INFORMATION TODAY.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> NOW TO OTHER NEWS OCCURRING
THIS WEEKEND.
ALLEGATIONS OF WIDESPREAD VOTER
FRAUD AS EGYPTIANS CAST BALLOTS
ON A NEW CONSTITUTION.
THE COUNTRY'S LEADER PREDICTS A
VICTORY IN THE REFERENDUM THEY
HOPE WILL END WEEKS OF VIOLENT
PROTESTS BUT SOME SAY COULD
SOLIDIFY A ISLAMIST STATE.
GREG IS LIVE WITH THE LATEST.
>> YEAH, IT SEEMS THE FOLKS IN
FAVOR OF THE CONSTITUTION ARE IN
THE LEAD.
THIS IS ONLY THE FIRST OF TWO
ROUNDS OF VOTING AND THE RESULTS
ARE PRELIMINARY.
BUT WHAT WE'RE SEEING IS THAT
THE YES VOTE GOT 57%, NO, 43%.
TURNOUT WAS LOW BY EGYPTIAN
STANDARD AND THE OPPOSITION
CLAIMS VARIES IRREGULARITIES.
AS WE'VE SEEN, WASHINGTON WAS
MARRED BY VIOLENCE.
HEADQUARTERS OF A SECULAR PARTY
ATTACKED BY ISLAMIST DESPITE
20,000 TROOPS IN THE STREET
TRYING TO KEEP THE PEACE.
>> WHAT'S THE GOVERNMENT SAYING
ABOUT THIS?
>> GOVERNMENT'S RESPONSE TO THAT
IS NOT TOO STRONG.
THEY'RE PUSHING FORWARD, WHICH
IS BASICALLY WHAT CRITICS ARE
SAYING, THEY'RE RAMMING IT
THROUGH.
NOW THEY'RE READY FOR THE NEXT
VOTE.
THIS IS A CONSTITUTION THAT'S
DIVIDED THIS NEW DEMOCRACY,
FAVORED BY MOHAMMED MORSI AND
THE MUSLIMS DEFENDERS SAY IT'S
NEEDED TO GAIN THE PROTECTION.
NEXT SATURDAY'S VOTING WILL
HAPPEN IN THE RURAL AREAS OF THE
COUNTRY, FAVORABLE TO THE
CONSERVATIVE ISLAMIST PARTY.
SO AT THIS POINT IT SEEMS THIS
CONSTITUTION'S GOING TO HAPPEN.
THERE ARE A CHANCES FOR THE
OPPOSITION TO MODIFY IT AFTER
THE FACT BUT THAT'S DIFFICULT.
THE NEW CONSTITUTION ALSO MEANS
THERE WILL BE A NEW PARLIAMENT
VOTED IN BUT ISLAMISTS ON THAT
SIDE ARE WELL ORGANIZED.
THE FEAR IS THAT THE OPPONENTS,
THE CRITICS, WILL AGAIN HAVE TO
TAKE IT TO THE STREETS.
>> ALL RIGHT, SO POTENTIALLY THE
VIOLENCE AND DEMONSTRATIONS MAY
NOT END.
>>> AS YOU HEARD GREG REPORT,
THE ISLAMIST PREDICTED TO SCORE
A VICTORY IN THE WEEKEND VOTE.
WHAT DOES IT MEAN FOR EGYPT'S
FUTURE, THE ROLE OF MORSI AND
THE POTENTIAL OF A ISLAMIST
STATE IN EGYPT.
JOHN BOLTON JONES US ABOUT EVERY
SUNDAY AT THIS TIME.
GOOD MORNING, EMBASSADOR.
>> GOOD MORNING.
>> THE NEW CONSTITUTION SAYS
ISLAM IS THE OFFICIAL RELIGION
OF THE STATE.
WHAT OTHER IMPACT IS THERE OF
THIS CONSTITUTION AND WHAT DOES
IT CALL FOR?
>> I THINK IT'S A SUBSTANTIAL
STEP TOWARD WHAT THE MUSLIM
BROTHERHOOD DESIRED, AND THAT IS
A EGYPT THAT COMES UNDER SHAHRY
ARE A LAW AND A NONDEMOCRATIC
STATE.
THERE WAS SPECULATION THE MORE
EXTREME EGYPTIANS WERE GOING TO
VOTE AGAINST THE CONSTITUTION
BECAUSE THEY DIDN'T BELIEVE IT
WAS SHARIA FRIENDLY ENOUGH.
THAT CLEARLY DIDN'T HAPPEN AND
IN THE SECOND ROUND, THERE'S NO
DOUBT THIS CONSTITUTION WILL BE
ADOPTED BY A MAJORITY OF THOSE
WHO VOTED.
SO I THINK THE PROSPECT IS THE
BROTHERHOOD WILL TRY TO
CONSOLIDATE POWER.
I THINK THERE'S EVERY PROSPECT
THE MILITARY AND BROTHERHOOD
WILL TRY TO CUT A DEAL.
I DON'T THINK THE MILITARY WANTS
TO SEE MORE VIOLENCE IN THE
STREETS.
THEY'VE HAD A VOTE, THIS IS WHAT
THE PRO DEMOCRACY PEOPLE WANTED.
HAD AN ELECTION, A REFERENDUM
AND VOTE AND THEY LOST.
I THINK THE BROTHERHOOD IS IN
VERY GOOD SHAPE IN TERMS OF
CONSOLIDATING POWER.
>> WHAT DOES THIS MEAN FOR US IF
INDEED EGYPT MOVES TO SHARIA LAW
AND POTENTIALLY RULED AND
GOVERNED BY THE MUSLIM
BROTHERHOOD?
>> THE DOMESTIC ISSUES IN EGYPT
ARE GRAVE FOR THE COP TICK
CHRISTIANS, FOR SECULAR
EGYPTIANS TO DON'T WANT A
RELIGIOUS STATE.
BUT I THINK THERE ARE ALSO
PROFOUND IMPLICATIONS FOR PEACE
AND STABILITY IN THE REGION FOR
THE FUTURE OF THE CAMP DAVID
PEACE ACCORD FOR ISRAEL.
FOR WHAT AID THEY GIVE TO
RADICAL ISLAMIST ELSEWHERE IN
THE REGION ACT THE NOT JUST
AGAINST ISRAEL BUT ARAB REGIMES
FRIENDLY TO THE UNITED STATES.
THERE ARE PROFOUND CONSEQUENCES
INTERNALLY AND EXTERNALLY IF
EGYPT KEEPS GOING.
>> DO YOU SEE WHAT'S HAPPENING
IN EGYPT AND IN SYRIA, FOR
EXAMPLE.
NEW RISE OF ISLAMIST THAT ARE
AGAINST OUR INTEREST.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
SYRIA IS A CASE WHERE IT MAY BE
A BLOW TO IRAN BUT GIVEN WHAT
WE'VE SEEN ABOUT RADICAL SUNY
ISLAMIST, WE'RE REPLACING ONE
BAD REGIME WITH ANOTHER.
THE IMPLICATIONS WILL SPREAD.
WE'VE SEEN IN LIBYA THE
INABILITY OF THE SUCCESSOR
GOVERNMENT TO GADHAFI TO CONTROL
THE ENTIRE TERRITORY.
SAME IN YEMEN.
THE RISK COULD CAUSE THE ENTIRE
MIDDLE EAST TO DESCEND INTO A
SITUATION OF NEAR ANARCHY WHERE
ALL THE VARIES CRISIS COME
TOGETHER.
>> YOU TALK ABOUT NEAR ANARCHY.
SIR WHERE SYRIA, LIBYA, WHAT CAE
OBAMA ADMINISTRATION DO AND WHAT
ARE THEY NOT DOING THAT THEY
SHOULD DO TOE STABILIZE IT.
>> I DON'T THINK THEY'RE PAYING
ADEQUATE ATTENTION.
IT'S MANIFESTATION OF THE FACT
THE PRESIDENT DOESN'T CARE ABOUT
NATIONAL SECURITY.
HIS PRIORITIES ARE DOMESTIC.
HE TURNS TO IT WHEN HE HAS TO
LIKE THE SEPTEMBER 11 KILLINGS
IN BENGHAZI BUT WE STILL DON'T
HAVE ANSWERS AS TO WHY ENHANCED
SECURITY WASN'T PROVIDED BEFORE
THE ATTACK AND HOW TO EXPLAIN
THIS STORY OF THE MOVIE ABOUT
THE PROPHET MUHAMMAD AS THE
CAUSE OF THE ATTACK.
I THINK IN EGYPT SPECIFICALLY WE
NEED TO TRY AND USE OUR
INFLUENCE ON THE EGYPTIAN
MILITARY TO STABILIZE THE
SITUATION.
AND TO USE ALL THOSE BILLIONS OF
DOLLARS OF AIDE WE'VE GIVEN OVER
THE YEARS TO TRY TO PREVENT THE
INTERNATIONAL SITUATION FROM
DETERIORATING FURTHER.
>> THERE'S LITTLE OR NO EVIDENCE
THE PRESIDENT'S PAYING
ATTENTION.
>> DO YOU THINK IT'S FAIR TO SAY
HE DOESN'T CARE ABOUT NATIONAL
SECURITY?
HE'S THE PRESIDENT.
>> HIS RECORD OVER THE PAST FOUR
YEARS, AS HE SAID DURING
THE 2008 CAMPAIGN, HE WANTED TO
FUNDAMENTALLY TRANSFORM AMERICA
AND THAT'S WHAT HE SET ABOUT
DOING.
I DON'T THINK HE'S UNCOMFORTABLE
WITH DECLINE IN AMERICAN
INFLUENCE INTERNATIONALLY.
THAT'S WHAT IS PLAYING OUT IN
THE MIDDLE EAST RIGHT NOW.
>> THE VOTE CONTINUES NEXT
SATURDAY LIKELY TO GO EVEN MORE
CONSERVATIVE.
EMBASSADOR BOLTON, ALWAYS GOOD
TO SEE YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> FOR THESE TWO HOURS WE'LL
CONTINUE TO FOLLOW THE LATEST IN
THE NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
SHOOTING MASSACRE AND THE
MASSIVE INVESTIGATION STILL
UNDER WAY.
IT INVOLVES LOCAL, STATE, AND
FEDERAL AGENTS FANNING OUT
ACROSS THE STATE CHASING LEADS
THEY HOPE WILL SHED LIGHT ON THE
TRAGEDY.
WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE
VICTIMS LIKE 6-YEAR-OLD EMILIE
PARKER, WHOSE GRIEVING FATHER
TALKED TO REPORTERS AFTER POLICE
RELEASED THE NAMES OF THE
VICTIM.
SOMEHOW HE FOUND THE STRENGTH TO
FORGIVE.
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Is bigger than we think ...
Sometimelike the flu.fer from
With aches, fever and chills-
the flu's a really big deal.
So why treat it like
it's a little cold?
There's something
that works differently
than over-the-counter
remedies.
Prescription TAMIFLU attacks
the flu virus at its source.
So don't wait. Call your
doctor right away.
TAMIFLU is prescription
medicine for treating the flu
in adults and children
one year and older
whose flu symptoms started
within the last two days.
Before taking TAMIFLU tell your
doctor if you're pregnant,
nursing. have serious
health conditions,
or take other medicines.
If you develop an allergic
reaction, a severe rash,
or signs of unusual behavior,
stop taking TAMIFLU and call
your doctor immediately.
Children and adolescents in
particular may be at an
increased risk
of seizures, confusion
or abnormal behavior.
The most common
side effects are
mild to moderate nausea
and vomiting.
The flu comes on fast,
so ask your
doctor about TAMIFLU.
Prescription for flu.
HOME STAYED CONNECTICUT, SENATOR
JOE LIEBERMAN TALKING ABOUT
TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN.
HE SAT DOWN WITH CHRIS WALLACE
ON "FOX NEWS SUNDAY" LAYING OUT
HIS VISION FOR THE WAY HE WANTS
THE GOVERNMENT TO DEAL WITH
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS.
>> THIS REMINDS ME OF THE DAYS
AND WEEKS AFTER THE TERRORIST
ATTACKS AGAINST US OF 9/11 AND
AT ONE POINT, JOHN McCAIN AND
I SAID WE CAN'T LET THIS GO.
WE'VE GOT TO CREATE A NATIONAL
COMMISSION TO INVESTIGATE
EXACTLY THE QUESTIONS WE'RE
ASKING ABOUT NEWTOWN.
HOW COULD THIS HAPPEN AND IS
THERE ANYTHING WE COULD DO TO
TRY TO PREVENT IT FROM HAPPENING
AGAIN?
>> JOINING ME, THE ANCHOR OF
"FOX NEWS SUNDAY," CHRIS
WALLACE.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
>> GOOD MORNING.
>> I WANT TO FOLLOW UP, THE
SENATOR THINKS WE SHOULDN'T
OVERLOOK IT.
WE TALKING ABOUT IT,
INVESTIGATING WHAT HAPPENED AND
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHERE WE GO
FROM HERE, BUT WEEKS FROM NOW
WHEN THERE'S OTHER NEWS, IS HE
OPTIMISTIC OUR GOVERNMENT WILL
MAKE CHANGES THAT WILL MAKE OUR
KIDS SAFER?
>> I DON'T SEE HOW YOU CAN BE
OPTIMISTIC.
WE'VE HAD SO MANY SHOOTINGS AND
OUTPORTION OF GRIEF AND NOTHING
HAPPENS.
CAN WE TAKE THIS AND TURN IT
INTO SOMETHING USEFUL?
LIEBERMAN CALLED FOR A NATIONAL
COMMISSION AND SOME PEOPLE ARE
SAYING THAT'S WHAT WE NEED,
ANOTHER COMMISSION.
IT'S A COMPLICATION ISSUE.
MENTAL HEALTH, THESE KIDS IN
EACH OF THESE CASES, MOST YOUNG
MEN, ALL WITH HISTORIES OF
MENTAL ILLNESS.
A LOT OF PEOPLE HAVE PERSONALITY
DISORDERS, AND IT DOESN'T MEAN
THEY'RE ABOUT TO SHOOT PEOPLE,
BUT HOW DO WE DETECT THE TIPPING
POINT WHEN THEY GO OVER THAT
LINE?
ALSO OUR CULTURE.
ALL OF US WHO HAVE KIDS SEE THEM
WITH THESE DARN VIDEO GAMES AND
MOVIES AND THINGS WHERE THEY'VE
SEEN THOUSANDS AND THOUSANDS OF
ACTS OF VIOLENCE ALL FICTIONAL
BUT OVER AND OVER BY THE TIME
THEY'RE TEN YEARS OLD.
THEN THERE'S THE GUNS.
IT'S NOT A SIMPLE ANSWER BUT --
GOSH, WE CAN'T LET THIS TO
CONTINUE TO HAPPEN AND HAPPEN
AND HAPPEN.
>> FORGIVE ME, FOR THE FIRST
TIME I DISAGREE.
I AGREE WITH YOU ON THE VIDEO
SITUATION BUT IF IT TURNS OUT
THIS MOTHER ACQUIRED THESE GUNS
AND TOOK HER SONS TO THE RANGE
TO LEARN HOW TO SHOOT, THAT SHE
WAS OBSESSED WITH SELF-DEFENSE,
I THINK IT STOPS WITH THE
PARENTS.
IN THIS PARTICULAR CASE, IT
COULD TURN OUT TO BE IT'S NOT
SYMPTOMATIC OF A MENTAL
DISORDER, LIKE YOU SAID, PLENTY
OF PEOPLE HAVE ASPERGER'S AND
THEY'RE HIGH FUNCTIONING.
MANY IT'S PARENTAL EDUCATION.
HE THINKS IT'S STRICTLY THE
GOVERNMENT'S RESPONSIBILITY?
>> OF COURSE NOT.
IT'S PART OF SOCIETY, IT'S PART
OF OUR RELIGIOUS TRAINING AND
PARENTS.
BUT YOU KNOW, JAMIE, A LOT OF
PARENTS TAKE THEIR KIDS TO GUN
RANGES AND SHOOT GUNS PERFECTLY
AND THEY DON'T INDIANA UP GET --
END UP GETTING UP, KILLING THEIR
MOTHER AND SLAUGHTERING 27
PEOPLE IN A SCHOOL.
THAT'S SOMETHING DEEPLY
DISTURBED ABOUT THIS KID OR THE
RELATIONSHIP IN THE FAMILY.
THERE ARE CERTAIN THINGS WE'LL
NEVER BE ABLE TO DO.
WE WOULDN'T WANT TO GO INTO
EVERY HOUSEHOLD AND POLICE IT.
WHETHER IT'S MENTAL HEALTH OR
THE DESENSITIZATION OF PEOPLE TO
VIOLENCE, PARTICULARLY YOUNG
MEN.
IT'S NOT THE RIGHT TO BEAR
ARMS -- AND A LOT OF PEOPLE
DISAGREE BUT WE SHOULD TALK
ABOUT THE IDEA THAT YOU CAN HAVE
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLES AND
HANDGUNS THAT CAN KILL SO MANY
PEOPLE QUICKLY.
>> I GUESS MY POINT IS YES, YOU
HAVE THE RIGHT TO HAVE ALL THOSE
THINGS UNLESS THEY FALL INTO THE
WRONG HANDS.
THIS MOTHER MAY HAVE BEEN THE
WRONG PERSON TO HAVE THESE
WEAPONS.
IN THE MEANTIME, A GREAT GUEST
TO HEAR SENATOR LIEBERMAN'S
TAKE.
>> LET ME SAY BEFORE WE GO,
WE'RE GOING TO TALK NOT JUST
WITH LIEBERMAN AND DURBIN AND
GUN CONTROL, WE TALK TO TWO SETS
OF PARENTS AND THEIR CHILD ABOUT
EXTRAORDINARY ACTS OF BRAVERY.
EXPERTS ON SCHOOL SAFETY.
ONE OF THE THINGS WE EMPHASIZE
IS THE PRINCIPAL WHO RAN TO THE
GUNFIRE, THE 27-YEAR-OLD FIRST
GRADE TEACHER WHO PUT HERSELF IN
FRONT OF THE SHOOTER TO PROTECT
THE KIDS.
THERE'S A LOT OF GOOD AND
STRENGTH.
>> TRUE HEROES.
WE'VE LEARNED A LOT.
THAT'S FOR SURE.
WE WILL FROM YOUR PROGRAM AS
WELL.
THANK YOU FOR BRINGING US A
PREVIEW.
>> "FOX NEWS SUNDAY" YOU CAN
CATCH CHRIS WALLACE'S INTERVIEW
WITH SENATOR LIEBERMAN AND HE
HAS DEMOCRATIC WHIP, SENATOR
DICK DURBIN AND THE FAMILIES.
YOU'LL WANT TO HEAR THEIR STORY.
>> THE AFTERMATH OF THIS
SHOOTING BRINGING THE ISSUE OF
MENTAL HEALTH TO THE FOREFRONT
OF OUR NATIONAL DISCUSSION.
HOW DO WE KNOW WHEN SOMEONE
NEEDS HELP?
HOW DO THEY GET IT?
CAN THIS BE FORCED TO?
WE WILL