SHORT WEEKS, THE FISCAL CLIFF IS
COMING TO TOWN ♪
♪ MERRY CLIFF MAS.
>> AND WITH A DRAMATIC NAME LIKE
FISCAL CLIFF, IT'S GOT TO BE
EXCITING!
JIM?
>> THE PRESIDENT'S ASKING FOR
$1.6 TRILLION IN REVENUE.
>> $600 BILLION IN TAX HIKES.
>> DIVIDENDS AND CAPITAL GAIN.
>> DISCRETIONARY SPENDING.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> SOMETIMES WE FEEL LIKE THAT.
BUT WE MAKE IT EXCITING.
THANKS FOR INVITING US INTO YOUR
HOME.
THAT'S IT FOR THIS SPECIAL
REPORT, FAIR, BALANCED AND
UNAFRAID.
>> THEY WERE JUST SIX YEARS OLD
AND AMONG THE DOZENS OF
INNOCENTS MURDERED IN THEIR
SCHOOL.
>> THEY'RE BABIES.
THEY'RE BABIES.
THEY'RE JUST BABIES.
>> TONIGHT HEARTBREAKING
GOOD-BYES IN CONNECTICUT.
INVESTIGATORS SAY THEY ARE
LOOKING AT EVERY BULLET, ANDING
EVERY ANGLE.
>> THE GUN PROCESSING THE
EVIDENCE, ANALYZING THE
EVIDENCE.
>> FROM THE WRECKAGE MUCH RUINED
LIVES, TRYING TO PIECE TOGETHER
UNDERSTANDING OF HOW THIS
HAPPENED.
PLUS WHAT, WE'VE LEARNED WITH
FRIDAY'S FIRST VICTIM.
THE SHOOTER'S OWN MOTHER.
SHE TOLD ME THE GUNS, SHE WOULD
TAKE THEM SHOOTING BECAUSE THAT
WAS A WAY THAT A SINGLE MOM
COULD, YOU KNOW, RELATE TO HER
SON.
>> SHE WAS DEVOTED AND THAT WAS
HER JOB, TO LOOK AFTER HIM.
>> TONIGHT THE INSIDE STORY FROM
THE FAMILY'S FRIENDS AND
NEIGHBORS.
I'M JOHN SCOTT IN FOR SHEPARD
SMITH.
WE BEGIN WITH THE SEARCH FOR A
MOTIVE.
IT IS CLEAR FRIDAY'S SHOOTING IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT CAN HAVE NO
RATIONAL EXPLANATION.
THE ACT ITSELF IS THE DEFINITION
OF INSANITY.
STILL AT THIS HOUR,
INVESTIGATORS ARE WORK TO
UNRAVEL THE SEQUENCE OF EVENTS
THAT ENDED WITH A MAN KILLING
HIS OWN MOTHER, DRIVING TO AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND MURDERING
26 INNOCENT CHILDREN AND ADULTS
BEFORE COMMITTING SUICIDE.
RIGHT NOW IT'S ALL STILL A
PUZZLE.
BUT INVESTIGATORS ARE WORKING TO
ASSEMBLE IT.
LAW ENFORCEMENT SOURCE TELLS THE
ASSOCIATED PRESS TEAMS ARE GOING
THROUGH THE SHORT'S COMPUTER AND
CHECKING PHONE AND CREDIT CARD
RECORDS IN AN ATTEMPT TO FIGURE
OUT WHAT HE WAS DOING AND WHAT
HE WAS THINKING IN THE DAYS AND
WEEKS BEFORE THIS ATTACK.
>> WE DID SEIZE SIGNIFICANT
EVIDENCE AT THE RESIDENCE.
WE ARE ANALYZING AND WILL
ANALYZE.
IT'S A VERY PAIN-STAKING
PROCESS.
>> A SPOKESMAN SAYS THE SHOOTER
TOOK CLASSES AT COMMUNITY
COLLEGE WHEN HE WAS 16 YEARS
OLD.
APPARENTLY DID WELL.
AN INTELLIGENT YOUNG MAN BY ALL
ACCOUNTS.
ON FRIDAY, SOMETHING WENT VERY
WRONG IN HIS HEAD.
POLICE SAY HE MURDERED HIS
MOTHER WHILE SHE WAS IN BED IN
HER PAJAMAS, THEN HE DROVE TO
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
CARRYING A VIRTUAL ARSENAL.
INVESTIGATORS SAY THE GUNMAN HAD
HUNDREDS OF ROUNDS OF AMMO WITH
HIM, PERHAPS ENOUGH TO KILL
EVERY STUDENT AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
THE CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR SAYS
WHEN THE GUNMAN HEARD POLICE
ARRIVING, HE USED ONE OF THOSE
BULLETS ON HIMSELF.
MASSACRE ENDING AS IT BEGAN,
WITH VIOLENCE AND BLOOD.
WE HAVE TEAM FOX COVERAGE WITH
RICK LEVENTHAL ON TODAY'S FIRST
FUNERALS FOR THE VICTIMS AND
UPDATES ON THE SURVIVORS.
FIRST, THE FOX REPORT'S CHIEF
CORRESPONDENT JONATHAN HUNT LIVE
AT THE FIRE HOUSE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WHERE DOES THE INVESTIGATION
STAND TONIGHT?
>> IT'S MOVING SLOWLY, JOHN, AND
IT'S MOVING METHODICALLY.
THERE ARE, OF COURSE, TWO MAIN
CRIME SCENES.
THE SCHOOL ITSELF WHERE THOSE 20
CHILDREN, AGES SIX AND SEVEN,
AND THE SIX FEMALE STAFF MEMBERS
WERE ALL GUNNED DOWN, SO
HORRIFICALLY ON FRIDAY.
THAT CRIME SCENE IS LIKELY TO
REMAIN ONE, ACCORDING TO THE
COPS, FOR MONTHS TO COME.
IT WILL NOT BE REOPENED AS A
SCHOOL UNTIL ALL OF THE
INVESTIGATIVE WORK IS DONE
THERE, IF IT REOPENS AS A SCHOOL
AT ALL.
THE SECOND CRIME SCENE, OF
COURSE, THE FIRST CHRISTIAN
LOGICALLY, IS ADAM LANZA'S HOME,
THE HOME IN WHICH HE WOKE UP ON
FRIDAY MORNING AND SHOT HIS
MOTHER IN THE HEAD FOUR TIMES.
HE APPARENTLY ALSO SMASHED A
COMPUTER.
COPS ARE LOOKING AT THAT, TOO,
FOR ANY EVIDENCE IT MAY GIVE
THEM.
ULTIMATELY THEY SAY THEY WILL
GET TO THE BOTTOM OF THIS
HORRIBLE INCIDENT.
LISTEN.
>> THE PEOPLE OF THIS TOWN OF
NEWTOWN WANT TO KNOW WHAT
HAPPENED.
WE'RE GOING TO DO THAT.
WE'RE GOING TO PROVIDE THEM ANY
INFORMATION AND ALL INFORMATION.
WE'LL PAINT A CRYSTAL CLEAR
PICTURE, AS MUCH AS WE POSSIBLY
CAN.
BUT IT IS A SLOW PROCESS.
>> NOW, TOP OF THE LIST OF
QUESTIONS, OF COURSE, IS DID
ADAM LANZA WAKE UP ON FRIDAY
MORNING AND IN SOME
EXTRAORDINARY FIT OF ANGER,
BEGIN HIS MURDEROUS RAMPAGE, OR
HAD HE PLANNED IT OVER SOME
TIME?
RIGHT NOW COPS DO NOT KNOW OR
ARE NOT GIVING US THE ANSWER TO
THAT CENTRAL QUESTION.
JOHN?
>> I KNOW YOU SPOKE WITH ONE OF
THE PSYCHOLOGISTS WORKING WITH
SOME OF THE SCHOOL CHILDREN.
HOW ARE THEY DOING?
>> YEAH.
INCREDIBLE CONVERSATION WITH
DR. JUDY.
SHE IS A CLINICAL PSYCHOLOGIST
WHO IS ATTACHED TO COLOMBIA
UNIVERSITY AND HAS WORKED WITH
THE UNITED NATIONS ON COUNSELING
KIDS IN THE WAKE OF DISASTERS
SUCH AS THE HAITI EARTHQUAKE,
INDONESIA TSUNAMI.
SHE'S HERE AND SPENT THE LAST
FEW DAYS IN ROOMS WITH SOME OF
THOSE CHILDREN WHO WERE IN SANDY
HOOK SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL ON FRIDAY.
SOME OF THOSE CHILDREN WHO HAD
TO WALK OUT PAST THE BODIES OF
HER CLASSMATES.
SHE TOLD ME SO MANY STORIES
ABOUT THEIR RESILIENCE, ABOUT
HOW THEY MAY OR MAY NOT BE ABLE
TO COPE WITH WHAT THEY HAVE
SEEN.
SHE TALKED ABOUT ONE
EXTRAORDINARILY TOUCHING SCENE
WHERE SHE WITNESSED CHILDREN
HELPING CHILDREN.
LISTEN.
>> WATCHING ONE CHILD COME IN, A
YOUNG BOY COME IN BEING VERY SHY
AND WITHDRAWN AND NOT WANTING TO
TALK TO ANYBODY AND HIS HEAD
DOWN AND HOLDING HIMSELF.
AND THEN WATCHING TWO YOUNG OF
HIS SCHOOL MATES, GIRLS, COME
RUSHING OVER TO HIM AND HUGGING
HIM.
HI, HOW ARE YOU?
AND JUST -- HE STARTED TO MELT A
LITTLE BIT.
AND THEY BROUGHT HIM OVER TO
WHERE THE TOYS WERE AND THEY
WERE TALKING TO HIM AND IT
BROUGHT HIM OUT OF HIS SHELL.
>> SHE SAYS EVERY CHILD REACTS
DIFFERENTLY IN THIS KIND OF
TRAUMATIC SITUATION, JOHN.
SHE SAYS THE BOTTOM LINE IS SOME
WILL HAVE THE RESILIENCE, THEY
WILL HAVE THE PARENTAL SUPPORT.
THEY WILL GET THROUGH THIS.
THEY WILL BE ABLE TO PUT IT AT
THE VERY BACK OF THEIR MINDS AND
LIVE LIKE N A SENSE, AS IF IT
NEVER REALLY HAPPENED BECAUSE
THEY ARE YOUNG ENOUGH.
FOR OTHERS, THOUGH, SHE SAYS
THEY WILL REMEMBER AND BE
SCARRED FOREVER BY WHAT THEY SAW
ON FRIDAY.
JOHN?
>> JONATHAN HUNT IN NEWTOWN.
THANK YOU.
LAST MONTH NOAH POZNER TURNED
SIX YEARS OLD.
TODAY HIS PARENTS BURIED HIM.
ONE OF TWO FUNERALS TODAY FOR
FIRST GRADERS.
HIS UNCLE SAID NOAH WOULD HAVE
BECOME A GREAT MAN AND GROWN UP
TO BE A GREAT DAD.
HIS FAMILY WILL NEVER KNOW THAT
HAPPINESS.
TODAY'S OTHER FUNERAL FOR JACK
PINTO, ALSO SIX YEARS OLD.
A BIG FAN OF THE NEW YORK
GIANTS.
THE GIANTS RECEIVER, VICTOR
CRUZ, TWEETED A PHOTO OF JACK'S
NAME, CALLING HIM MY HERO.
HIS ONE OF COUNTLESS TRIBUTES TO
THE INNOCENT VICTIMS OF FRIDAY'S
ATTACK.
RICK LEVENTHAL IS LIVE IN SANDY
HOOK.
WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT THE TWO
SHOOTING VICTIMS WHO SURVIVED?
>> INITIALLY THE REPORTS WERE
THERE WAS ONLY ONE GUNSHOT
VICTIM WHO SURVIVED.
IN FACT, THERE WERE TWO WOMEN
WHO WERE BOTH HIT IN THEIR LOWER
EXTREMITIES, BOTH WERE
HOSPITALIZED AND BOTH HAVE NOW
BEEN SENT HOME.
POLICE ARE NOT RELOOSING THEIR
IDENTITIES, BUT DO PLAN TO TALK
TO THEM AS SOON AS THEY'RE WELL
ENOUGH TO ANSWER QUESTIONS ABOUT
THE EVENTS.
ALSO TODAY, AS YOU MENTIONED,
THE VERY LONG AND DIFFICULT
PROCESS OF FUNERALS AND BURIALS
BEGAN WITH TWO SIX-YEAR-OLD BOYS
BEING EULOGIZED AND LAID TO
REST.
JACK PINTO REMEMBERED AS A
GIANTS FANS WITH ENERGY AND
STEELY DETERMINATION.
AND NOAH POZNER, WHOSE TWIN
SISTER AND EIGHT-YEAR-OLD SISTER
ALSO ATTENDED SANDY HOOK.
THE GIRLS SURVIVED, BUT THEIR
BROTHER DID NOT.
>> HE WAS CELEBRATED AS A PURE,
INNOCENT CHILD, LIKE A PROMISE
OF LIFE AHEAD OF HIM WHO BROUGHT
JOY TO HIS FAMILY AND TO HIS
COMMUNITY AND WILL BE SORELY
MISSED.
AND AS HIS OLDER BROTHER SAID,
HE COULD HAVE BEEN ANYTHING IF
HE WOULD HAVE GROWN OLDER.
IT'S A TRAGEDY OF EPIC
PROPORTIONS AND WE HAVE NO
ANSWERS FOR THIS.
>> TWO MORE FUNERALS ARE
SCHEDULED HERE IN NEWTOWN
TOMORROW.
>> THE GOVERNOR ATTENDED ONE
TODAY?
>> YEAH.
THE GOVERNOR SAID THAT YOU TRY
TO FEEL THEIR PAIN, BUT YOU
CAN'T.
THAT WORDS ARE INADEQUATE AND
THE LITTLE COFFINS ARE HEART
BREAKING AND HE SAID THE
SHOOTINGS ON FRIDAY COULD LEAD
TO A CHANGE IN GUN LAWS.
>> THERE REALLY ARE NO WORDS TO
DESCRIBE WHAT IT'S LIKE TO SEE
THESE PARENTS AS I DID ON
FRIDAY, LAST NIGHT GOING FROM
ROOM TO ROOM, AND THEN AGAIN
WITH RESPECT TO NOAH'S PARENTS
TODAY.
>> THE GOVERNOR SAYS THIS COMING
FRIDAY AT 9:30 A.M., THE ENTIRE
STATE OF CONNECTICUT WILL
OBSERVE A MOMENT OF SILENCE AND
EVERY HOUSE OF WORSHIP IS BEING
ASKED TO TOLL ITS BELLS 26 TIMES
FOR EACH OF THE VICTIMS KILLED
AT SANDY HOOK.
>> THAT SCHOOL IS STILL CLOSED
TONIGHT.
WHAT'S THE PLAN TO GET THE KIDS
BACK IN CLASS?
>> WELL, AS JONATHAN HUNTS
MENTIONED, SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
IS STILL A CRIME SCENE.
THERE IS NO WORD ON IF OR EVER
IT WILL REOPEN.
BUT IN THE MEANTIME, THERE WERE
MOVING VANS THAT WENT TO THE
SCHOOL TODAY TO UNLOAD EVERY
SINGLE PIECE OF FURNITURE, THE
DESKS, THE CHAIRS, THE SUPPLIES,
MOVING EVERYTHING OUT OF SANDY
HOOK AND TAKING IT TO CHALK
HILL,  WHICH IS A FORM MIDDLE
SCHOOL IN MONROE,  WHICH IS
SEVEN MILES AWAY.
THAT SCHOOL BEING REFURBISHED
AND SHOULD BE READY FOR THE
SANDY HOOK KIDS LATER.
THE GOVERNOR SIGNING AN
EXECUTIVE ORDER TO MAKE THIS
SWITCH POSSIBLE AS EARLY AS
TOMORROW.
>> LET'S HOPE IT WORKS FOR THEM
AS EARLY AS POSSIBLE.
THANKS.
>>> THE OWNERS OF A RESTAURANT
IN NEWTOWN SAY THEY'VE BEEN
GETTING CALLS FROM ALL OVER FROM
FOLKS ASKING TO DONATE MONEY TO
THE VICTIMS' RELATIVES.
>> PEOPLE CALLING FROM ALL OVER
THE COUNTRY AND ALL OVER THE
WORLD WANTING TO HELP THE
FAMILIES IN NEWTOWN.
WE GOT A CALL FROM SWITZERLAND,
PAKISTAN, CHICAGO, MINNESOTA,
NEW JERSEY.
>> THE OWNERS OF MY PLACE PIZZA
AND RESTAURANT ARE OBLIGING.
THEY'RE TAKING CREDIT CARD
NUMBERS AND USING THE MONEY TO
BUY LUNCHES FOR THE VICTIMS'
FAMILIES.
THE OWNERS SAY THEY'LL DONATE
ANY LEFTOVER FUNDS TO A FUND
FORM THE SANDY HOOK FAMILIES.
BUT THEY ALSO ENCOURAGED FOLKS
TO DONATE TO LARGER
ORGANIZATIONS THAT ARE MORE
EXPERIENCED WITH HELPING PEOPLE.
FOR SOME THOSE WAYS TO LEND A
HAND, LOG ON TO FOXNEWS.COM ON
OUR HOME PAGE.
YOU'LL SEE A LINK CALLED HOW TO
HELP.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID LAST
NIGHT WE NEED TO CHANGE TO
PREVENT VIOLENCE LIKE THIS.
ARE AMERICANS READY FOR STRICTER
GUN LAWS?
NEW POLL SHOWS WHERE PEOPLE
STAND.
WHY GUN CONTROL MAY JUST BE A
PART OF THE WHITE HOUSE PLAN.
THAT'S COMING UP ON THE FOX
REPORT.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a
Droid Incredible 4G LTE
by HTC for $49.99.
WHO HAVE USED AndroGel 1%,
THERE'S BIG NEWS.
PRESENTING AndroGel 1.62%.
BOTH ARE USED TO TREAT MEN
WITH LOW TESTOSTERONE.
AndroGel 1.62%
IS FROM THE MAKERS
OF THE NUMBER ONE PRESCRIBED
TESTOSTERONE
REPLACEMENT THERAPY.
IT RAISES YOUR TESTOSTERONE
LEVELS, AND...
IS CONCENTRATED,
SO YOU COULD USE LESS GEL.
AND WITH AndroGel 1.62%,
YOU CAN SAVE
ON YOUR MONTHLY PRESCRIPTION.
[ Male Announcer ]
DOSING AND APPLICATION SITES
BETWEEN THESE PRODUCTS DIFFER.
WOMEN AND CHILDREN SHOULD AVOID
CONTACT WITH APPLICATION SITES.
DISCONTINUE AndroGel
AND CALL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU SEE UNEXPECTED SIGNS
OF EARLY PUBERTY IN A CHILD,
OR, SIGNS IN A WOMAN
WHICH MAY INCLUDE
CHANGES IN BODY HAIR
OR A LARGE INCREASE IN ACNE,
POSSIBLY DUE TO
ACCIDENTAL EXPOSURE.
MEN WITH BREAST CANCER
OR WHO HAVE OR MIGHT HAVE
PROSTATE CANCER,
AND WOMEN WHO ARE,
OR MAY BECOME PREGNANT
OR ARE BREAST FEEDING
SHOULD NOT USE AndroGel.
SERIOUS SIDE EFFECTS
INCLUDE WORSENING
OF AN ENLARGED PROSTATE,
POSSIBLE INCREASED RISK
OF PROSTATE CANCER,
LOWER SPERM COUNT,
SWELLING OF ANKLES, FEET,
OR BODY,
ENLARGED OR PAINFUL BREASTS,
PROBLEMS BREATHING
DURING SLEEP,
AND BLOOD CLOTS IN THE LEGS.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT YOUR MEDICAL CONDITIONS
AND MEDICATIONS,
ESPECIALLY INSULIN,
CORTICOSTEROIDS, OR MEDICINES
TO DECREASE BLOOD CLOTTING.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR TODAY
ABOUT AndroGel 1.62%
SO YOU CAN USE LESS GEL.
LOG ON NOW
TO AndroGelOffer.com
AND YOU COULD PAY AS LITTLE
AS TEN DOLLARS A MONTH
FOR AndroGel 1.62%.
WHAT ARE YOU WAITING FOR?
THIS IS BIG NEWS.
OMNIPOTENT OF OPPORTUNITY.
YOU KNOW HOW TO MIX BUSINESS...
WITH BUSINESS.
AND YOU...RENT FROM NATIONAL.
BECAUSE ONLY NATIONAL LETS YOU
CHOOSE ANY CAR IN THE AISLE.
AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE A FULL-SIZE
OR AVE.
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
I COULD GET USED TO THIS.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, YOU COULD BUSINESS PRO.
YES, YOU COULD.
GO NATIONAL. GO LIKE A PRO.
>> John: RARE QUIET ON WHAT'S
USUAL LEA BUSTLING TRADING
FLOOR.
THEY PAUSED FOR A MOMENT, A
SOMBER TRIBUTE TO THOSE WHO DIED
FRIDAY.
OTHER THAN A YEARLY REMEMBRANCE
OF THE ATTACKS OF 9-11, THIS IS
WALL STREET'S FIRST MOMENT OF
SILENCE SINCE THE MASS SHOOTINGS
IN TUCSON NEARLY TWO YEARS AGO.
JUST MOMENTS AGO, THE HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES OBSERVED A
MOMENT OF SILENCE FOR THE
VICTIMS.
MEMBERS ARE ALSO TAKING UP A
RESOLUTION TO HONOR THE DEAD.
>> MOST AMERICANS NOW SAY THEY
SUPPORT MORE RESTRICTIONS ON
GUN, THAT'S ACCORDING TO A NEW
POLL FROM THE "WASHINGTON POST"
AND ABC NEWS.
54% SAY THEY FAVOR STRICTER GUN
CONTROL LAWS.
43% SAY THEY OPPOSE THEM.
THE POLLSTERS SAY THEY DID THE
SURVEY THIS PAST WEEKEND.
MOSTLY AFTER THE MASSACRE AT
SANDY HOOK.
LAST NIGHT PRESIDENT OBAMA SPOKE
AT A VIGIL IN NEWTOWN AND SAID
THE NATION HAS TO DO MORE TO
KEEP THIS FROM HAPPENING AGAIN.
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS, I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT TO MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS, TO PARENTS
AND EDUCATORS IN AN EFFORT AIMED
AT PREVENTING MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS.
>> John: TODAY THE WHITE HOUSE
SAID GUN CONTROL IS ONLY PART OF
THE PRESIDENT'S PLAN.
ED HENRY LIVE AT THE WHITE HOUSE
FOR US.
I GUESS PRESS SECRETARY JAY
CARNEY WOULDN'T GET TOO SPECIFIC
ABOUT THAT PLAN TODAY.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
LOOK, THE PRESIDENT GOT HIGH
MARKS FOR THOSE REMARKS HE
MENTIONED LAST NIGHT AT THAT
PRAYER VIGIL.
I WAS THERE.
ACROSS THE POLITICAL SPECTRUM,
PEOPLE WERE SAYING IT'S PERHAPS
STRUCK THE RIGHT TONE.
MAYBE THERE WILL BE SOME ACTION.
BUT THERE IS A WAY TO HAVE A
REASON DEBATE TO FIND OUT THE
BEST SOLUTION.
JAY CARNEY, WHEN PRESSED TODAY
ON EXACTLY WHAT THE PRESIDENT IS
GOING TO DO, WAS NOT VERY
SPECIFIC AT ALL.
DIDN'T HAVE A CLEAR BATTLE PLAN
AT ALL.
SO DIDN'T EVEN HAVE A TIME LINE
OF HOW QUICKLY HE WOULD MOVE.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> I THINK THAT IT'S PART OF IT,
BUT IT IS FAR FROM ALL OF IT.
AS YOU KNOW, THE PRESIDENT HAS
TAKEN POSITIONS ON COMMON SENSE
MEASURES THAT HE BELIEVES SHOULD
BE TAKEN TO HELP ADDRESS THIS
PROBLEM, BUT HE MADE CLEAR THAT
MORE NEEDS TO BE DONE.
>> THAT WAS A QUESTION ABOUT GUN
CONTROL, NOT AS SPECIFIC AND
FIRM IN TERMS OF THE PRESIDENT
LAST NIGHT, SAYING THAT HE
REALLY WANTS TO DO SOMETHING TO
PROTECT CHILDREN, ALTHOUGH WE'RE
TOLD THAT THIS AFTERNOON, THE
PRESIDENT, THE VICE PRESIDENT
SAT DOWN WITH A FEW CABINET
SECRETARIES HERE AT THE WHITE
HOUSE TO FIGURE OUT WHAT THEY
MIGHT DO IN THE DAYS AHEAD.
IT WASN'T JUST THE ATTORNEY
GENERAL WHO WOULD HANDLE GUN
CONTROL.
ALSO EDUCATION SECRETARY AND THE
HEALTH SECRETARY.
THAT SUGGESTS THEY'RE TAKING A
BROADER LOOK, PERHAPS ALSO
LOOKING AT MENTAL HEALTH AND
OTHER ISSUES.
>> A MAJOR DEVELOPMENT WORKS
CENTRIST DEMOCRATS WITH A
RATINGS FROM THE NRA SAY THEY
WANT MORE GUN CONTROL?
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
MARK WARNER OF VIRGINIA SAYS HE
THINKS THIS WAS GAME CHANGER
BECAUSE OF THE NUMBER OF
CHILDREN INVOLVED.
HE'S A MODERATE DEMOCRAT WHO WAS
OPPOSED TO GUN CONTROL AND NOW
SAYS HE'S READY TO LOOK AT IT.
JOE MANCHIN OF WEST VIRGINIA
SAYING MUCH THE SAME.
HE ALSO SAID WHILE HE'S BEEN
OPPOSED TO GUN CONTROL, HE
THINKS IT NEEDS TO BE LOOKED AT
NOW.
THERE NEEDS TO BE SOME KIND OF
ACTION FOR BOTH SIDES TO COME
TOGETHER AND MAYOR MICHAEL
BLOOMBERG, WHO HAS BEEN
OUTSPOKEN, WAS ASKED ABOUT
WHETHER THE FISCAL CLIFF AND
OTHER ISSUES WILL PUSH GUN
CONTROL TO THE BACK BURNER.
HE MOCKED THAT IDEA.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> IF CONGRESS AND THE PRESIDENT
CAN'T FOCUS ON TWO THINGS AT
ONCE, WHO ON EARTH DID WE ELECT?
>> ONE THING THAT MIGHT FIND
BIPARTISAN SUPPORT IS DIANE
FEINSTEIN SAYS SHE'LL
REINTRODUCE A BAN ON ASSAULT
WEAPON WHICH IS PEOPLE ACROSS
THE POLITICAL SPECTRUM HAVE SAID
GO A BIT MAR.
MAYBE THEY NEED TO BE RAINED IN.
AND THE WHITE HOUSE IS SAYING
THAT'S ONE SPECIFIC THING THE
PRESIDENT WOULD SUPPORT.
>> John: ED HENRY TONIGHT.
THANKS.
>>> TEAM FOX COVERAGE ON THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING CONTINUES AHEAD,
KELLOGG WARNING TO KIDS AT A NEW
JERSEY SCHOOL.
DON'T LET STRANGERS IN THE
BUILDING.
JUST ONE WAY SCHOOL OFFICIALS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY ARE
RETHINKING WAYS TO KEEP KIDS
SAFE.
PLUS, TENSE MOMENTS FOR SCHOOLS
ONE OF THE
COUNTRY.
TODAY COPS IN CALIFORNIA SAYING
THEY BUST ADD POTENTIAL COPY
CAT.
DETAILS COMING UP NEXT
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THE MERCEDES-BENZ WINTER EVENT
IS BACK,
WITH THE PERFECT VEHICLE
THAT'S JUST RIGHT FOR YOU,
NO MATTER WHICH LIST YOU'RE ON.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
C250 FOR $349 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
AWW MAN.
[ Male Announcer ] RETURNS
ARE EASY WITH FREE PICKUP
FROM THE U.S. POSTAL SERVICE.
WE'LL EVEN DROP OFF BOXES
IF YOU NEED THEM.
VISIT USPS.COM
PAY, PRINT,
AND HAVE IT PICKED UP FOR FREE.
ANY TIME OF YEAR.
♪
NICE SWEATER.
THANK YOU.
♪
>> John: TODAY IN CALIFORNIA,
POLICE ANNOUNCED THEY HAVE
ARRESTED A POTENTIAL COPY CAT
AFTER THE DEADLY SHOOTING IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THEY SAY HE POSTED THREATS ON
FACEBOOK TARGETING ELEMENTARY
SCHOOLS IN LOS ANGELES.
WHEN THEY FOUND HIM AT HIS
PARENTS' HOME, THIS ALSO CAME
ACROSS NOT ONE, BUT NINE
FIREARMS, INCLUDING RIFLES AND A
SHOTGUN.
TRACE GALLAGHER IS LIVE ON OUR
WEST COAST NEWS ROOM.
WE'RE GETTING BREAKING NEWS FROM
THE DISTRICT ATTORNEY.
>> YEAH.
WE JUST GOT THIS FROM THE D.A.
THE D.A. IS NOW SAYING THEY ARE
NOT GOING TO FILE CHARGES
AGAINST 24-YEAR-OLD KYLE AND THE
REASON WHY IS BECAUSE HE DIDN'T
MAKE A SPECIFIC THREAT TOWARD A
SPECIFIC SCHOOL OR CHILD.
THE DEAL IS THAT HE POSTED ON
FACEBOOK SEVERAL TIMES AFTER THE
CONNECTICUT SHOOTING THAT IF
OTHER PEOPLE DIDN'T STOP POSTING
ABOUT IT, HE WAS GOING TO GO OUT
AND DO THE SAME THING.
TELLING PEOPLE ON FACEBOOK THAT
THOUSANDS OF THIRD WORLD
CHILDREN DIED EVERY DAY AND THAT
THEY SHOULD GET OVER IT.
BUT THEN WHEN POLICE AS YOU
SAID, WENT TO HIS PARENTS'
HOUSE, THEY FOUND THOSE NINE
WEAPONS.
THE D.A. IS NOT FILING CHARGES.
THE L.A.P.D
DID NOT THINK HE WAS JOKING.
LISTEN.
>> HE WAS CLEAR IN HIS
STATEMENTS AND HIS ABILITY
MATCHED THOSE STATEMENTS.
THIS WAS NOT A PERSON THAT WAS
UNARMED.
THIS WAS NOT A PERSON THAT DID
NOT HAVE A CLEAR AND PRESENT
ABILITY TO MAKE GOOD ON HIS
THREATS.
>> YEAH.
BY THE WAY, THIS KYLE ALSO
WORKED FOR A COMPANY CALLED
KUMAN, WHICH TOURS CHILDREN.
THE COMPANY SAYS HE WAS NOT AN
INSTRUCTOR, THAT HE WAS AN
EMPLOYEE.
IT'S UNCLEAR EXACTLY HOW MUCH
CONTACT HE HAD WITH THOSE KIDS.
JOHN?
>> John: HOW IS THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT RESPONDING?
>> WELL, FORTUNATELY, MOST OF
THE SCHOOLS IN LOS ANGELES
COUNTY ARE ON HOLIDAY BREAK
RIGHT NOW.
BUT THE SCHOOLS THAT ARE IN
SESSION ARE CLEARLY GETTING SOME
UPTICK IN POLICE PRESENCE.
IN FACT, THERE MIGHT BE SOME BIG
WHOLESALE CHANGES.
HIGH SCHOOLS IN LOS ANGELES ALL
HAVE POLICE OFFICERS ON CAMPUS.
NOW THE DISTRICT IS TALKING
ABOUT POSSIBLY HAVING POLICE
OFFICERS AT MIDDLE SCHOOLS, EVEN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS.
LISTEN.
>> WE ARE FOCUSED HERE IN L.A.
AT PROVIDING OUR PARENTS AND OUR
GUARDIANS WITH ABSOLUTE SENSE OF
ASSURITY OF SAFETY.
SO WE HAVE SPECIFIC MEASUREMENTS
AROUND SAFETY ON OUR CAMPUS.
>> AGAIN, THE BREAKING NEWS IN
ALL THIS IS THAT THE D.A. AND
L.A. HAS NOW DECIDED THAT HE
DOES NOT HAVE ENOUGH EVIDENCE TO
PRESS CHARGES.
JOHN?
>> John: TRACE GALLAGHER IN OUR
WEST COAST NEWS ROOM.
THANK YOU.
>>> JUST SOUTH OF L.A., A GUNMAN
THIS WEEKEND FIRED OFF DOZENS OF
ROUNDS IN A MALL PARKING LOT.
THAT HAPPENED SATURDAY AFTERNOON
IN NEWPORT, BEACH.
PEOPLE RAN FROM THE SCENE
DUCKING FOR COVER AS UNLOADED
SHOTS INTO THE AIR AND GROUND.
AUTHORITIES PUT THE MALL ON
LOCKDOWN.
COPS SAY THE SUSPECT DROPPED THE
GUN AND, QUOTE, GAVE UP WHEN
OFFICERS ON BICYCLES APPROACHED
HIM.
NOBODY HURT.
POLICE ARRESTED THE GUY AND
RECOVERED A HAND GUN AND
AMMUNITION AT THE SCENE.
THE SUSPECT IS REPORTEDLY A
LICENSED SECURITY GUARD WHOSE
FIREARM PERMIT EXPIRED BACK IN
2001.
>>> THE MOTHER OF THE SHOOTER IN
CONNECTICUT TOOK HIM TO GUN
RANGES AND A APPARENT ATTEMPT TO
BOND WITH HER TROUBLED SON.
THAT'S FROM A FAMILY FRIEND TO
FOX NEWS.
AS WE LEARN MORE ABOUT NANCY
LANZA'S RELATIONSHIP WITH HER
SON AND WHY SHE ONCE WARNED A
BABY-SITTER NEVER TO LEAVE HIM
ALONE.
PLUS A FORMER U.S. MARINE BEHIND
BARS IN MEXICO AND CHAINED TO A
BED.
COMING UP, OUR FIRST LOOK AT THE
MISERABLE CONDITIONS FOR AN
AMERICAN PRISONER TRAPPED IN A
FOREIGN LAND.
THAT'S COMING UP AS WE APPROACH
THE BOTTOM OF THE HOUR AND THE
TOP OF THE NEWS
[ Male Announcer ] Alka-Seltzer
Plus PRESENTS THE Cold Truth.
I HAVE A COLD,
AND I TOOK NYQUIL,
BUT I'M STILL "STUBBED" UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT DOESN'T HAVE A DECONGESTANT.
NO WAY.
[ Male Announcer ] SORRY.
Alka-Seltzer Plus FIGHTS
YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A FAST ACTING
DECONGESTANT
TO RELIEVE YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
[ sighs ] THANKS!
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus.
♪ OH
WHAT A RELIEF IT IS! ♪
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
AND SAVE $1
VISIT Alka-Seltzer ON FACEBOOK.
[ A Hybrid? Most areO LEARN
MORE just no fun to drive.
Now, here's one that will
make you feel alive.
Meet the five-passenger
Ford C-MAX Hybrid.
C-MAX says ha.
C-MAX says wheeee.
Which is what you get,
don't you see?
Cause C-MAX has lots more
horsepower than Prius v,
a hybrid that C-MAX
also bests in MPG.
Say hi to the all-new 47
combined MPG C-MAX Hybrid.
THEY DON'T HELP SINGLE MOMS.
HI!
[ Sarah ] WHAT HAPPENED
TO OUR HOUSE LAST YEAR?
[ Daughters ] IT FLOODED
AND THE WATER FLOODED OUT. YEAH.
[ Sarah ] THE RED CROSS
ARRANGED THE HOTEL FOR US.
THEY GAVE ME THAT BREAK,
THAT LEVERAGE,
TO BE ABLE TO GET IT TOGETHER
AND TAKE CARE OF THEM. YOU KNOW?
I FEEL LIKE WE'VE COME
FULL CIRCLE.
[ Daughter 1 ] LIKE THAT!
[ Daughter 2 ]
THIS IS HOW I'LL DO IT.
[ Sarah ] THERE YOU GO.
>> John: BIG DEVELOPMENTS
OVERSEAS.
FIRST ISSUES THE VICE PRESIDENT
OF SYRIA TOLD A LEBANESE
NEWSPAPER HE DOES NOT THINK HIS
MILITARY CAN DEFEAT THE REBELS.
THAT THE ASSAD REGIME MAY BE
PLANNING SOME SORT OF EXIT
STRATEGY.
PRO-GOVERNMENT FORCES HAVE BEEN
BATTLING REBEL FORCES FOR NEARLY
TWO YEARS.
HUMAN RIGHTS ACTIVISTS CLAIM
MORE THAN 40,000 PEOPLE HAVE
DIED.
THE LATEST CONCERN HAS BEEN
WHETHER THE SYRIAN MILITARY
WOULD USE CHEMICAL WEAPONS ON
ITS OWN PEOPLE IN A LAST DITCH
EFFORT TO STAY IN POWER.
BUT TODAY SYRIA'S AMBASSADOR TO
THE UNITED NATIONS WARNED THAT
THE REBELS MIGHT TRY USING
CHEMICAL WEAPONS AND THEN BLAME
THE GOVERNMENT IN AN ATTEMPT TO
GAIN MORE SUPPORT.
>>> EGYPT IS BRACING FOR
WIDESPREAD PROTESTS TOMORROW
AGAINST THE COUNTRY'S NEW POT
AND ITS NEWLY DRAFTED
CONSTITUTION.
DEMONSTRATIONS RAGED ON AGAINST
MOHAMMED MORSI.
OPPONENTS CLAIM HE TRIED TO MAKE
HIMSELF A DICTATOR BY GRANTING
HIMSELF NEAR ABSOLUTE POWER.
OVER THE WEEKEND, VOTERS PASSED
THE NEW CONSTITUTION WITH 57% OF
THE BALLOT.
IF PASSED IF AN UPCOMING VOTE,
HIS ALLY ALSO HAVE SWEEPING NEW
POWERS.
PROTESTERS CLAIM THE VOTE WAS
FULL OF IRREGULARITIES.
THEY ARE DEMANDING THE PRESIDENT
STEP DOWN AND THE CONSTITUTION
BE REWRITTEN.
>>> I'M JOHN SCOTT IN FOR
SHEPARD SMITH.
THIS IS THE FOX REPORT.
THE MOTHER OF THE SHOOTER IN
FRIDAY'S SCHOOL MASSACRE KNEW
HER SON HAD PROBLEMS.
SO MUCH SO SHE DIDN'T LIKE TO
LEAVE HIM ALONE.
THAT FROM A MARRIAGE COUNSELOR
WHO DEALT WITH THE MOTHER'S
DIVORCE.
HER ACCOUNT IS JUST ANOTHER
PIECE OF THE TROUBLING PUZZLE
THAT IS STARTING TO TAKE SHAPE.
ACCORDING TO THE REPORTING OF
CBS NEWS A MAN WHO BABY SAT THE
SHOOT SERVICE A TEEN-AGER SAYS
NANCY LANZA ONCE WARNED HIM NOT
TO TURN HIS BACK ON HER SON FOR
A MOMENT.
NOT EVEN TO GO TO THE BATHROOM.
AS WE'VE BEEN REPORTING, FAMILY
FRIENDS DESCRIBED THE
20-YEAR-OLD AS A SOCIALLY
AWKWARD LONER.
THEY SAY HE SUFFERED FROM
ASPERGER SYNDROME.
A FRIEND WHO HAS A SON WITH
AUTISM SAYS THE SHOOTER'S MOM
SOMETIMES TALKED ABOUT SOME OF
HER STRUGGLES.
>> NANCY WOULD GET UPSET BECAUSE
HER SON REFUSED TO LET HER TOUCH
HIM.
SHE COULDN'T HUG HIM.
WHERE MY SON JUST THE OPPOSITE.
SHE'D SEE MY SON HANGING ALL
OVER ME.
BUT AUTISTIC KIDS, EACH AND
EVERY ONE OF THEM IS DIFFERENT.
>> John: NOW INVESTIGATORS ARE
POURING OVER EVERY DETAIL OF THE
SHOOTER'S RELATIONSHIP WITH HIS
MOTHER, SEARCHING FOR ANY CLUE
INTO WHY HE SHOT HER IN THE HEAD
BEFORE TURNING THOSE GUNS ON
INNOCENT KIDS.
MOLLY LINE WITH THE NEWS LIVE AT
THE FIRE HOUSE MEMORIAL IN
NEWTOWN.
WE KNOW THE SHOOTER GOT THE GUNS
HE USED FROM HIS MOTHER.
WHAT ELSE ARE YOU LEARNING?
>> WE HAD A CHANCE TO SPEAK WITH
SOME OF NANCY LANZA'S FRIENDS
TODAY.
MANY OF THEM HUNG OUT WITH HER
AT A LOCAL PUB AND THEY SAID SHE
WAS A PRETTY NORMAL WOMAN, MA
THANK SHE DID HAVE AN INTEREST
IN GUNS AND SHOOTING GUNS AND
THAT SHE HAD TAKEN HER SON TO DO
THAT, THAT IT WAS A BONDING TYPE
OF THING BETWEEN MOTHER AND SON.
BUT TODAY FEDERAL AUTHORITIES
WITH THE ATF SAID THAT THERE WAS
NO EVIDENCE THAT ADAM LANZA HAD
BEEN TO A GUN RANGE AT ALL IN
THE LAST SIX MONTHS OR SO.
ONE OF HER FRIENDS SAID THAT
WHILE SHE WAS INTERESTED IN
WEAPONS AND GUNS, IT WASN'T A
BIG PART OF HER LIFE.
BUT SHE DIDN'T TALK ABOUT IT TOO
OFTEN.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> SHE'S BEEN DESCRIBED I THINK
AS SOME KIND OF GUN, YOU KNOW,
ENTHUSIAST, GUN NUT, SURVIVALIST
OR THINGS THAT I'VE HEARD.
THAT'S JUST NOT THE NANCY I
KNOW.
I KNOW SHE HAS GUNS AND SHE
ENJOYS TARGET SHOOTING AND
THAT'S ALL I KNOW.
IT'S NOT HER PRIMARY HOBBY.
>> THE FRIENDS THAT WE SPOKE
WITH ALSO SAID THAT NANCY HADN'T
TALKED ABOUT HER SON BEING
DANGEROUS OR VIOLENT IN ANY WAY.
SHE HADN'T EXPRESSED ANY FEAR.
JOHN?
>> John: WHAT DID THE MOTHER
TELL THE FRIENDS ABOUT THE
CHALLENGES THAT SHE FACED IN
RAISING THIS KID?
>> SHE DID TALK ABOUT HIM QUITE
A BIT AND ABOUT THE STRUGGLE AS
FAR AS GETTING HIM AN ADEQUATE
EDUCATION R HIS PATH IN LIFE
WITH LEAD HIM, WE SPOKE WITH TWO
FRIENDS THROUGHOUT THE DAY THAT
SAID SHE WAS CONSIDERED EVEN
MOVING IN THE UPCOMING YEARS IF
HE FOUND A COLLEGE THAT WAS
RIGHT FOR HIM.
APPARENTLY HAD TAKEN SOME
COMMUNITY COLLEGE COURSES.
BUT IF HE FOUND THE DEGREE HE'D
LIKE TO PURSUE THAT SHE WOULD
UPROOT AND MOVE TO A PLACE WHERE
HE WOULD BE ABLE TO DO THAT.
JOHN.
>> John: MOLLY.
THANK YOU.
SEVERAL SCHOOLS NOT FAR FROM THE
SCENE OF FRIDAY'S MASSACRE WENT
ON LOCKDOWN THIS MORNING T.
HAPPENED AFTER REPORTS OF A MAN
CARRYING A RIFLE NEAR A SCHOOL
IN RIDGEFIELD, CONNECTICUT,
20 MILES SOUTHWEST OF NEWTOWN.
AUTHORITIES FROM SEVERAL TOWNS
HELPED COPS RESPOND.
AFTER HOURS OF SEARCHING, POLICE
SAY THEY ARRESTED A MAN DRESSED
ALL IN BLACK WHO WAS CARRYING AN
UMBRELLA THAT LOOKED LIKE A
SAMURAI SWORD.
NOBODY HURT.
POLICE ENDED THE LOCKDOWN AROUND
NOON.
>>> THIS JUST ONE EXAMPLE OF THE
AFRAID NERVES AS STUDENTS RETURN
TO CLASSROOMS FOR THE FIRST TIME
SINCE FRIDAY'S SHOOTING IN WHAT
SCHOOLS REVIEWING WAYS TO BETTER
PROTECT OUR STUDENTS.
JAMES ROSEN IS LIVE IN
WASHINGTON WITH MORE ON THAT.
JAMES?
>> GOOD EVENING.
EDUCATORS AND ADMINISTRATORS AT
PUBLIC AND PRIVATE SCHOOLS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY STROVE TO
REASSURES PARENTS THAT THEIR
SCHOOLS AND KIDS ARE SAFE.
PROCEDURES FOR SAFETY DRILLS
WERE DUSTED OFF AND REVISITED.
LOCAL POLICE TOUCHED BASE WITH
SCHOOL SECURITY OFFICERS.
THE MESSAGE TO PARENTS WAS WE'RE
TRAINED FOR INCIDENTS LIKE THIS.
>> AS A RESULT OF SOME OF THE
NEW PROCEDURES IN PLACE, I THINK
THERE HAVE BEEN SEVERAL
INSTANCES SINCE COLUMBINE THAT
WERE STOPPED AS A RESULT OF A
HEIGHTENED AWARENESS OF SCHOOL
VIOLENCE.
>> WHILE SOME SCHOOLS OBSERVED A
MOMENT OF SILENCE, MANY
PRINCIPALS OPTED NOT TO RAISE
NEWTOWN AS THE SUBJECT WITH
SCHOOL CHILDREN.
MY OWN SON'S PRINCIPAL IN THE DC
AREA WROTE TO PARENTS LAST
NIGHT, QUOTE, OUR APPROACH WILL
BE TO ADDRESS IT AS IT COMES UP
ORGANICALLY WITH STUDENTS.
SOME OF THE CHILDREN WILL HAVE
HEARD AND/OR SEEN DETAILS OF THE
EVENT ON TV, WHILE OTHERS MAY
HAVE BEEN SHIELDED FROM THE
MAJORITY OF THE INFORMATION.
I DO NOT WANT ADULT INITIATED
CONVERSATIONS TO IMPRESS MORE ON
THE CHILDREN THAN PARENTS
DESIRE.
>> WE ALSO HAVE TO BE WATCHING
OUT FOR CHILDREN BECAUSE
ESPECIALLY WITH YOUNG CHILDREN,
IT MAY NOT BE WITH WORDS THAT
THEY ASK THEIR QUESTIONS.
IT MAY BE WITH THEIR BEHAVIOR.
>> SO EXPERTS SAY IF CHILDREN
ASK YOU ABOUT NEWTOWN, KEEP YOUR
ANSWERS SHORT AND SIMPLE AND TO
EMPHASIZE THEY AND THEIR SCHOOLS
ARE SAFE.
JOHN.
>> John: JAMES ROSEN, THANKS.
WE NEVER LEAVE A BATTLE BEHIND.
THAT'S THE BATTLE CRY.
FOR WHAT FRIENDS AND FAMILY
CALLED TRUMPED UP CHARGES.
JON HAMMER'S CRIME REPORTEDLY
CARRYING AN ANTIQUE RIFLE DURING
A VACATION TO HELP TREAT HIS
POSTTRAUMATIC STRESS DISORDER.
MENTAL WOUNDS HE SUFFERED WHILE
SERVING MULTIPLE TOURS IN IRAQ
AND AFGHANISTAN.
NOW HIS SUPPORTERS HAVE TURNED
TO SOCIAL MEDIA TO TRY TO WIN
HIS FREEDOM.
PHIL KEATING LIVE IN OUR SOUTH
FLORIDA NEWS ROOM WITH MORE ON
THAT.
IS THE MEXICAN GOVERNMENT
FEELING THE PRESSURE HERE, PHIL?
>> IT IS.
NOT SURE HOW MUCH IMPACT THAT'S
HAVING.
BUT THE PRESSURE IS COMING FROM
OUR OWN CONGRESS, STATE
DEPARTMENT, AND THE MEDIA, WHICH
IS NOW BROADCAST AGO BRAND-NEW
PHOTO OF THE FORMER MARINE
SHACKLED TO HIS PRISON BED
ACROSS THE BORDER FROM MEXICO.
THIS IS 27-YEAR-OLD JON HAMMER.
IN THE WORDS OF HIS MOTHER WHO
HAS SEEN THIS PHOTO, HIS EYES
NOW LOOK A LITTLE LOST.
THAT PRISON ACROSS THE TEXAS
BORDER IN MATAMOROS WHERE HIS
SURFING TRIP TO COSTA RICA WAS
INTERRUPTED.
FACEBOOK AND TWITTER ARE ASKING
THOUSANDS OF FOLLOWERS TO HELP
FREE JON HAMMER.
>> YOU KNOW, WE'RE TRYING NOT TO
GET OUR HOPES UP OR JOHN'S HOPES
UP BECAUSE IT'S JUST SO
DEFLATING WHEN NOTHING HAPPENS.
BUT AT THIS POINT, WE'RE JUST
BEGGING THE MEXICAN GOVERNMENT.
>> HAMMER IS CHARGED WITH A
FELONY FOR ALLEGEDLY BRINGING IN
A WEAPON ACROSS THE BORDER
WITHOUT ANY PERMITS RIGHT INTO
VIOLENCE-PLAGUED MEXICO.
HIS TRIAL DATE IS SCHEDULED FOR
NEXT MONTH.
>> John: WE'VE GOT CHRISTMAS
COMING UP IF A WEEK.
WHAT ARE THE CHANCES HE COULD BE
BACK IN FLORIDA BY THEN?
>> HIS MEXICAN ATTORNEY BELIEVES
THERE IS A GOOD CHANCE HE HAS
FILED TWO FEDERAL INJUNCTIONS
AND HE HOPES A COURT WILL RULE
IN THEIR FAVOR, PERHAPS BY
THURSDAY.
MEANWHILE, THE MEXICAN
AMBASSADOR TO THE UNITED STATES
SENT THIS LETTER TO MIAMI
CONGRESSWOMAN WHICH READS,
QUOTE:  I MUST UNDERSCORE THAT
INTRODUCING TO AND/OR POSSESSING
WEAPONS OF THIS KIND OF MEXICO,
REGARDLESS OF INTENT, IS
CONSIDERED A SERIOUS OFFENSE.
HE WAS CAUGHT AT THE BORDERED
WITH A SHOTGUN IN HIS WINNEBAGO
WHICH HIS FAMILY SAYS WAS FOR
BIRD HUNTING.
BUT THE GUN MAY HAVE BAN SAWED
OFF SHOTGUN AND TOO SHORT.
THE VETERAN HAS BEEN LOCKED UP
SINCE THIS HAPPENED IN AUGUST.
MEXICAN AUTHORITIES SAY THE ONLY
REASON THAT PHOTO SHOWS HIM
SHACKLED WITH THAT LONG CHAIN TO
HIS PRISON BED IS BECAUSE HE WAS
MOVED OUT OF THE GENERAL INMATE
POPULATION, WHICH IS HEAVY AND
RICH WITH DRUG CARTEL INMATES
OVER TO A LESS SECURE AREA FOR
HIS OWN SAFETY.
JOHN.
>> John: PHIL KEATING IN MIAMI.
THANK YOU.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA AND HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER GETTING
TOGETHER AGAIN TO TRY TO PULL US
BACK FROM THE BRINK OF THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
NOW THERE IS WORD SPEAKER
BOEHNER MAY BE BUDGING, AT LEAST
A LITTLE, WHEN IT COMES TO
RAISING TAXES ON THE RICHEST
AMERICANS.
BUT WE'RE ALSO HEARING LAWMAKERS
MAY HAVE TO WORK CHRISTMAS WEEK
TO GET A DEAL DONE.
A LIVE UPDATE FROM CAPITOL HILL
NEXT ON THE FOX REPORT
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN IT COMES TO
THE FINANCIAL OBSTACLES
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAN
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
LooShriners Hospitals have how
everything  to do with that.
I was in an accident.
I was burned.
I lost my hands, my feet.
I really thought my
life was over.
Shriners did a lot more
than just heal me.
They helped me put my whole
life back together.
Caitlin's life is one of
nearly a million
changed by donations from
people like you.
Send your love to the rescue.
Donate today.
but with ADVAIR,
I'm breathing better.
So now I can be in
the scene.
ADVAIR is
clinically proven to help
significantly improve
lung function.
Unlike most COPD medications,
ADVAIR contains both an
anti-inflammatory
and a
long-acting bronchodilator
working together to help improve
your lung function all day.
ADVAIR won't
replace fast-acting inhalers
for sudden symptoms
and should not be used more
than twice a day.
People with
COPD taking ADVAIR
may have a higher chance
of pneumonia.
ADVAIR may increase your
risk of osteoporosis
and some eye problems.
Tell your doctor
if you have a heart condition
or high blood pressure before
taking ADVAIR.
If you're still
having difficulty breathing,
ask your doctor if including
ADVAIR could help
improve your lung function.
Get your
first full
prescription
free
and save
on refills
at
ADVAIRcopd.com.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME R CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
WHAT STARTS
WITH ADDING A FRIEND...
♪
...COULD END
WITH ADDING A CLOSE FRIEND.
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
>> John: JOHN BOEHNER PAYING
ANOTHER VISIT TO PRESIDENT OBAMA
AT THE WHITE HOUSE.
WITH 15 DAYS TO GO 'TIL WE ARE
SET TO PLUNGE OFF THE SO-CALLED
FISCAL CLIFF, HE'S OFFERING TO
LET TAX CUTS EXPIRE FOR PEOPLE
MAKING MORE THAN A MILLION
DOLLARS A YEAR.
BUT THE PRESIDENT IS DEMANDING A
RATE HIKE ON INCOME OF MORE THAN
250,000.
THE WHITE HOUSE AND CONGRESS
CANNOT CUT A DEAL, TAX CUTS
EXPIRE FOR EVERYBODY TWO WEEKS
FROM TOMORROW.
MIKE EMMANUEL IS LIVE ON CAPITOL
HILL.
MIKE, WHAT CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT
THIS MEETING BETWEEN THE SPEAKER
AND THE PRESIDENT?
>> JOHN, THEY KEPT A PRETTY GOOD
LID ON IT.
NOT MUCH INFORMATION.
BUT THAT MAY BE A GOOD SIGN.
SPEAKER BOEHNER DID NOT SPEAK TO
REPORTERS WHEN HE RETURNED TO
CAPITOL HILL AFTER A 45-MINUTE
WHITE HOUSE MEETING WITH
PRESIDENT OBAMA LATE THIS
MORNING.
THE KEY MOMENT IN TALKS MAY HAVE
COME FRIDAY WHEN SPEAKER BOEHNER
OFFERED TO RAISE TAXES ON THOSE
MAKING MORE THAN A MILLION
DOLLARS.
WE KNOW THE WHITE HOUSE HAS
WANTED TO INCREASE TAXES ON
PEOPLE MAKING MORE THAN
$250,000.
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS MOMENTS AGO
CAME OUT WITH AN OFFER THAT THE
PRESIDENT MAY HAVE OFFERED BACK
TO SPEAKER BOEHNER SAYING HE'D
BE WILLING TO RAISE TAXES ON
THOSE MAKING MORE THAN $400,000.
SO YOU SEE MOVEMENT IN BOTH
DIRECTIONS.
AT THE WHITE HOUSE, PRESS
SECRETARY JAY CARNEY HINTED MORE
TAX MONEY IS NEEDED.
>> IT IS ALSO THE CASE THAT WE
HAVE NOT SEEN A PROPOSAL BESIDES
THE PRESIDENT'S, THAT ACHIEVES
THE BALANCE THAT THE PRESIDENT
INSISTS BE PART OF A DEAL.
>> HARRY REID TODAY WARNED HIS
COLLEAGUES THAT HE'S EXPECTING
TO BE BACK TO WORK ON
DECEMBER 26, THE DAY AFTER
CHRISTMAS, ON THE FISCAL CLIFF.
WE'LL SEE IF THAT MOVES THEM TO
ACTION.
JOHN.
>> John: SO IS THERE A ROUGH
OUTLINE OF A DEAL HERE?
I MEAN WHAT, CAN YOU TELL US
ABOUT THAT?
>> YES, WE HAVE GOTTEN A SENSE
OF A ROUGH OUTLINE, ACCORDING TO
THE SOURCES CLOSE TO SPEAKER
BOEHNER.
HERE IS A LOOK AT IT.
$1 TRILLION IN CUTS.
$1 TRILLION IN REVENUE.
AND IMMEDIATE DOWN PAYMENT AND
LEGISLATIVE PROCESS THROUGH NEXT
YEAR.
IT COULD ALSO INCLUDE THE DEBT
CEILING INCREASE, UNEMPLOYMENT
INSURANCE, THE DOC FIX, THE
PAYROLL TAX CUT, AND TAX
EXTENDERS AND SO EVERYBODY IS
SAYING THIS IS A BROAD OUTLINE
BURKS THE REAL STICKING POINT
SEEMS TO BE THE TAX REVENUE
ISSUE AND AGAIN, THE ASSOCIATED
PRESS REPORTING MOMENTS AGO
THERE IS A NEW OFFER ON THE
TABLE FROM THE PRESIDENT.
JOHN?
>> John: MIKE EMMANUEL AT THE
U.S. CAPITOL, THANK YOU.
>> AS LAWMAKERS STRUGGLE TO FIX
THE DEBT PROBLEMS, THEY ARE ALSO
BATTLING OVER A PROPOSED
SPENDING BILL THAT AIMS TO
PROVIDE BILLIONS OF DOLLARS TO
AID TO THOSE WHO ARE STILL
RECOVERING FROM HURRICANE SANDY.
OF COURSE, THE SUPER STORM
DEVASTATED PARTS OF THE
NORTHEAST IN LATE OCTOBER
CAUSING TRILLIONS IN DAMAGE AND
DESTROYING HUNDREDS OF HOMES AND
BUSINESSES.
DEMOCRATS LAST MONTH BEGAN
CALLING FOR MORE FEDERAL AID.
BUT REPUBLICANS SAY THE SPENDING
BILL IS LOADED WITH MILLIONS OF
DOLLARS IN SPENDING UNRELATED TO
SANDY'S DEVASTATION.
DOUG McKELWAY HAS MORE ON
THAT.
>> GOOD EVENING.
THE DEBATE OVER FUNDING FOR
SANDY RECOVERY COULD BE A SUPER
STORM IN ITS OWN RIGHT UNDER THE
CAPITOL BILL.
THE SENATE BEGAN DEBATE OVER
SUPPLEMENTAL SPENDING BILL THAT
WOULD PROVIDE $60.4 BILLION IN
AID.
BUT FISCAL CONSERVATIVES ARE
RESISTING, SAYING SANDY RELIEF
MONEY NEEDS TO BE OFFSET WITH
CUTS ELSE.
>> IT JUST DOESN'T MAKE SENSE
RIGHT NOW.
WE'RE BROKE.
WE NEED TO BE SMARTER ABOUT WHAT
MONEY IS NEEDED.
>> DEMOCRATS COUNTER THAT
OFFSETTING DISASTER RELIEF
SPENDING WOULD BE UNPRECEDENTED.
THAT YOU WOULD NEVER BE ABLE TO
APPROPRIATE DISASTER MONEY IF
YOU HAD TO PIT IT AGAINST AN
EXISTING FEDERAL PROGRAM.
DEMOCRATS ALSO ARGUE THAT
REPUBLICANS IN THEIR EAGERNESS
TO SAVE MONEY ARE IGNORING THE
HUMANNESS OF THE DISASTER.
>> TALK TO THE PERSON WHOSE
HOUSE HAS BEEN DESTROYED AND
IT'S A WEEK BEFORE THE CHRISTMAS
SEASON AND IT'S GETTING COLD.
TELL THEM.
>> REPUBLICANS POINT OUT
DEMOCRATS HAVE ALSO INCLUDED
SUCH NONSANDY RELATED EXPENSES
AS $25 MILLION TO REHABILITATE
FARM LAND DAMAGED BY UNSPECIFIED
NATURAL DISASTERS, $58 MILLION
TO RESTORE PRIVATE FOREST LAND
DANIELED BY NATURAL DISASTERS,
NOT NECESSARILY SANDY.
AND $200 MILLION FOR HEALTH AND
HUMAN SERVICES TO BE USED AT THE
DISCRETION OF THE SECRETARY.
NORTHEAST SENATORS ARE PUTTING
GREAT PRESSURE ON THE HOUSE TO
PASS THIS BILL.
THE SHOWERS MOVING AT ITS OWN
PASS.
THEIR VERSION OF THE BILL HASN'T
GOTTEN OUT OF THE APPROPRIATIONS
YET.
>> John: AND THE HORSE TRADING
GOES ON.
>>> HILLARY CLINTON IS ON THE
MEND AFTER SHE SUFFERED A
CONCUSSION.
THAT'S THE WORD FROM THE STATE
DEPARTMENT.
BUT THAT MEANS SHE WILL NOT
TESTIFY THIS WEEK AS PLANNED ON
THE DEADLY ATTACK IN BENGHAZI,
LIBYA.
WE'LL HAVE THE LATEST ON A KEY
INDEPENDENT REVIEW OF THAT
ATTACK.
PLUS REPUBLICAN LAWMAKERS
ANNOUNCED WHO WILL TAKE OVER THE
SENATE SEAT HELD BY THE TEA
PARTY FAVORITE JIM DEMINT, NOW
THAT HE'S RESIGNING AND THE GOP
MADE A HISTORIC CHOICE.
DETAILS AHEAD ON THE FOX REPORT
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>> John: THE STATE DEPARTMENT
REPORTS ITS REVIEW OF THE ATTACK
ON THE U.S. OUTPOST IN
BENEFITING IS FINISHED AND ON
ITS WAY TO SECRETARY OF STATE
HILLARY CLINTON.
THE ATTACK KILLED THE U.S. AM
WAS TORE TO LIBYA, CHRIS STEVENS
AND THREE OTHER AMERICANS.
WE'RE ALSO EXPECTING MEMBERS OF
CONGRESS TO GET COPIES OF THE
REPORT.
A SPOKESWOMAN SAYS SECRETARY
CLINTON WILL NOT TESTIFY ON
CAPITOL HILL THIS WEEK BECAUSE
SHE'S RECOVERING FROM A
CONCUSSION.
CATHERINE HERRIDGE LIVE NOW.
HOW DID THE SECRETARY WIND UP
WITH A CONCUSSION?
>> THANK YOU, AND GOOD EVENING.
IN THIS LETTER TO THE HEADS OF
THE HOUSE AND SENATE FOREIGN
AFFAIRS COMMITTEE, SECRETARY OF
STATE HILLARY CLINTON HELD UP
THE POSSIBILITY SHE MAY TESTIFY
IN THE FUTURE BURKS OFFERED NO
DATES CERTAIN.
BUT IT WAS EMPHASIZED SHE WANTED
TO GO TO CAPITOL HILL, BUT A
STOMACH VIRUS, DEHYDRATION, THEN
A FAINTING SPELL AND HIT HER
HEAD.
THIS IS HOW THE STATE DEPARTMENT
TRIED TO EXPLAIN IT.
>> THE SECRETARY HAD ANTICIPATED
TESTIFYING.
SHE HAD COMMITTED TO DO SO WITH
THE TWO COMMITTEE CHAIRSES.
AS WE PUT OUT ON SATURDAY, SHE
IS STILL UNDER THE WEATHER.
SHE WAS DIAGNOSED AS HAVING
SUFFERED A CONCUSSION AND HER
DOCTORS HAVE URGED HER TO STAY
HOME THIS WEEK.
>> CLINTON IS AT HOME RECOVERING
FROM HER CONCUSSION, HER AIDES
SAY SHE IS REVIEWING THE
FINDINGS OF THE INDEPENDENT
INVESTIGATION INTO THE BENGHAZI
TERRORIST ATTACK, WHICH IS NOW
COMPLETE.
TWO DEPUTIES WILL TESTIFY IN HER
PLACE THIS WEEK ABOUT THE
FINDINGS.
>> John: SO COULD SHE STILL
TESTIFY BEFORE SHE LEAVES
OFFICE?
>> WELL, IT'S POSSIBLE.
ON SUNDAY THE HEAD OF THE HOUSE
FOREIGN AFFAIRS COMMITTEE SAYING
CLINTON MUST TESTIFY, ADDING
IT'S BEEN A STRUGGLE TO KEEP THE
PROCEEDINGS OPEN.
>> THAT'S BEEN THE PROBLEM WITH
THE ADMINISTRATION THUS FAR IS
THAT THEY WANTED TO HAVE ALL OF
THE HEARINGS AND ALL OF THE
BRIEFINGS IN A SECURED SETTING,
BUT THE AMERICAN PEOPLE WANT TO
KNOW WHAT THE STATE DEPARTMENT
AND ALL OF OUR AGENCIES ARE
DOING TO KEEP OUR DIPLOMATS
SAFE.
>> ON SEPTEMBER 16, FIVE DAYS
AFTER THE ATTACK THAT KILLED
FOUR AMERICANS, INCLUDING THE
U.S. AMBASSADOR, U.N. AMBASSADOR
SUSAN RICE TOOK CLINTON'S PLACE.
SHE SAID SHE WAS ASKED TO SUB,
CITING CLINTON'S WORK SCHEDULE.
THE BOTTOM LINE IS CLINTON HAS
BEEN UNAVAILABLE ON TWO KEY
OCCASIONS TO SPEAK ON THE
ADMINISTRATION'S BEHALF ON THE
TERRORIST ATTACK IN BENGHAZI.
>> John: CATHERINE HERRIDGE IN
WASHINGTON, THANK YOU.
>>> NIKKI HALEY MAKING A
HISTORIC CHOICE TO REPLACE
REPUBLICAN SENATOR JIM DEMINT.
SHE'S APPOINTING GOP CONGRESSMAN
TIM SCOTT.
HE'LL BE THE 7th
AFRICAN-AMERICAN SENATOR IN U.S.
HISTORY.
SENATOR DEMINT IS RESIGNING IN
JANUARY TO RUN THE HERITAGE
FOUNDATION, A CONSERVATIVE THINK
TANK IN D.C
YOU CAN HEAR MORE FROM THEM WHEN
THEY GO ON THE RECORD WITH GRETA
VAN SUSTEREN TONIGHT 10:00 P.M.
EASTERN HERE ON FOX NEWS
CHANNEL.
>>> THE SENATE'S LONGEST SERVING
MEMBER WHO WAS IN LINE FOR THE
PRESIDENCY IS PART OF THE LINE
OF SUGGESTION CESS HAS DIED.
HAWAII DEMOCRAT DANIEL INWAY
DIED IN WASHINGTON.
HE HAD REPRESENTED HAWAII SINCE
IT BECAME A STATE IN 1959.
HE WAS ITS VERY FIRST
CONGRESSMAN AND NINE-TEMPLE
SENATOR.
THE U.S. PUT HIS JAPANESE
PARENTS IN AN ININTERNMENT CAMP
DURING WORLD WAR II.
HE JOINED THE U.S. ARMY, LOST
HIS RIGHT ARM IN THE WAR, AND
WON THE MEDAL OF HONOR.
HE ALSO SERVED ON THE WATERGATE
COMMITTEE AND HE WAS THE ONLY
MEMBER TO ASK THE QUESTION THAT
WAS SUPPOSED TO BE THE WHOLE
PURPOSE OF THE PANEL.
QUOTE, WOULD YOU CARE TO
RECOMMEND TO THIS COMMITTEE ANY
LEGISLATION TO PREVENT THE
RECURRENCE OF SOME OF THE
IRREGULARITIES THAT OCCURRED IN
THE 1972 PRESIDENTIAL ELECTION?
TONIGHT VERMONT DEMOCRAT PATRICK
LEAHY HAS TAKEN HIS PLACE AS
THIRD IN LINE FOR THE
PRESIDENCY.
SENATOR DANIEL INOUYE WAS 88
YEARS OLD.
HIS LAST WORD WAS ALOHA
EVERYTHT
THE ORAL-B POWER BRUSH
IS SIMPLY REVOLUTIONARY.
OUR UNIQUE BRUSH HEAD CLEANS
IN THREE DIRECTIONS
WITH UP TO 50% MORE
BRUSH MOVEMENTS
THAN LEADING
SONIC TECHNOLOGY.
ORAL-B POWER BRUSHES.
GO TO ORALB.COM
FOR THE LATEST OFFERS.
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
FLAVOR, MEET FOOD.
IT'S TIME
FOR SWANSON FLAVOR BOOST.
CONCENTRATED BROTH
IN EASY TO USE PACKETS.
MIX IT INTO SKILLET DISHES,
FOR AN INSTANT DOSE OF...
HELL-O!
[ Female Announcer ]
GET RECIPES AT FLAVORBOOST.COM.
>> John: THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT IS CALLING FOR A
MOMENT OF SILENCE THIS FRIDAY,
EXACTLY ONE WEEK AFTER GUN SHOTS
RIPPED APART SO MANY LIVES IN
HIS STATE.
GOVERNOR MALLOY IS ALSO ASKING
CHURCHES TO RING THEIR BELLS 26
TIMES IN MEMORY OF ALL THOSE WHO
DIED AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
BACK NOW TO JONATHAN HUNT LIVE
IN NEWTOWN.
>> JOHN, THE VICTIMS OF THIS
HORRIFIC ATTACK ARE BEING AND
WILL CONTINUE TO BE MEMORIALIZED
IN MANY WAYS HERE.
MAKESHIFT TRIBUTES HAVE SPRUNG
UP ALL OVER THIS SMALL TOWN,
INCLUDING ONE BEHIND ME WHICH
INCLUDES 26 CHRISTMAS TREES, ONE
FOR EACH OF THE VICTIMS AT THAT
SCHOOL.
I WE'VED AS A FAMILY LAID
FLOWERS THERE TODAY.
THE FATHER THEN TELLING ME THAT
HIS DAUGHTER WOULD HAVE BEEN AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY ON FRIDAY,
BUT SHE HAD A DENTAL
APPOINTMENT.
MEANTIME, THE FIRST OF MANY
FUNERALS HAVE TAKEN PLACE.
NOAH POZNER AND JACK PINTO LAID
TO REST HERE IN NEWTOWN TODAY.
AND THE INVESTIGATION, OF
COURSE, CONTINUES.
IT IS GOING SLOWLY.
IT IS GOING METHODICALLY.
TWO CRIME SCENES, THE SCHOOL
ITSELF WHERE THE 20 CHILDREN
AGES SIX AND SEVEN WERE ALL
GUNNED DOWN BRUTALLY, ALONG WITH
SIX FEMALE STAFF MEMBERS.
THE SECOND CRIME SCENE, THE
SHOOTER'S HOME, ADAM LANZA WOKE
UP ON FRIDAY MORNING THERE, SHOT
HIS MOTHER FOUR TIMES WE ARE
TOLD, IN THE HEAD, THEN TOOK THE
WEAPONS THAT BELONGED TO HER,
WENT TO THE SCHOOL AND CONTINUED
HIS MURDEROUS RAMPAGE.
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE PROMISES
ANSWERS IN THIS INVESTIGATION,
BUT WITH THE SHOOTER HAVING
KILLED HIMSELF, THERE MAY NEVER
BE AN ANSWER TO THE BIGGEST
QUESTION:  WHY?
>> John: THANKS.
>>> ON THIS DAY IN 1843, A
HOLIDAY CLASSIC WAS BORN, WITH
THE PUBLICATION OF THE CHARLES
DICKENS "A CHRISTMAS CAROL."
AVENUES REPORTER BEFORE HE
BECAME A FAMOUS AUTHOR.
WHILE WRITING FOR NEW