AND ALL THE PARENTS I TALKED TO
TODAY ABOUT THIS SHOOTING IN
THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SAID ONE
THING, LIKE JAMES ROSEN'S MOM
SAID, THEY'RE GOING TO HUG THEIR
KIDS TIGHTER TONIGHT.
THERE IS A MEMORIAL SERVICE IN A
FEW MINUTES IN NEWTOWN.
WE'RE GOING TO SHOW THAT YOU
LIVE.
20 FAMILIES THERE SENT THEIR
KIDS TO GRADE SCHOOL THIS
MORNING LIKE ANY OTHER DAY AND
TONIGHT THEY'RE NOT COMING HOME.
11 NIGHTS FROM CHRISTMAS ON THIS
THE SEVENTH NIGHT OF HANUKKAH.
A HOLY TIME OF THE YEAR.
WHETHER YOU OBSERVE THESE
HOLIDAYS OR NOT, TONIGHT THE
THOUGHTS AND PRAYERS OF THIS
NATION ARE WITH THE VICTIMS AND
THEIR FAMILIES, FAIR, BALANCED
AND UNAFRAID.
>> THIS IS THE FOX REPORT.
TONIGHT MASS MURDER AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
DOZENS ARE DEAD AFTER A GUNMAN
OPENED FIRE ON CHILDREN.
>> JUST AFTER 9:30 THIS MORNING,
NEWTOWN POLICE RECEIVED A 911
CALL.
>> IT HAPPENED JUST AS THE
SCHOOL DAY WAS BEGINNING.
>> THEY DIDN'T TELL US ANYTHING.
>> I JUST HEARD THE PRINCIPAL
WAS SHOT AND KILLED.
MY SON WAS IN THE GYM WHEN IT
HAPPENED.
>> THEY RUSHED THE KIDS INTO THE
BATHROOM AND THEY LOCKED THE
DOOR.
>> BY THE TIME THE GUN FIRE
ENDED, BLOOD AND BODIES WERE
EVERYWHERE.
>> I KNOW THERE IS NOT A PARENT
IN AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
>> TONIGHT THE SHOOTING SPREE AT
A GRADE SCHOOL.
I'M BILL HEMMER.
EVENING, IN FOR SHEPARD SMITH.
WE'RE LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, SMALL TOWN, 90
MINUTES NORTH OF MANHATTAN THAT
RIGHT NOW IS DEALING WITH THE
AFTERMATH OF AN UNSPEAKABLE
CRIME.
THE MURDER OF INNOCENT CHILDREN.
IT HAPPENED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY, CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE SAYING A GUNMAN WALKED
INTO THAT K THROUGH FOURTH GRADE
SCHOOL EARLIER TODAY, AROUND
9:30 LOCAL TIME, AND OPENED
FIRE.
INVESTIGATORS SAY HE MURDERED 20
CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS.
>> THE KIDS WERE TERRIFIED.
THEY WERE TERRIFIED.
THEY HAD JUST WITNESSED
SOMETHING AND THEY
TERRIFIED.
>> MANY OF THEM WERE FRIENDS OF
OURS AND PEOPLE WE SOCIALIZE
WITH.
IT'S PAINFUL RIGHT NOW.
>> 20 CHILDREN.
THIS IMAGE SHOWS CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE LEADING CHILDREN
AWAY FROM THE SCHOOL, EACH OF
THEIR SMALL HANDS ON THE
SHOULDERS OF THE CHILDREN IN
FRONT OF THEM AS THEY WALK FROM
THE SCENE WHERE A MAD MAN KILLED
THEIR FRIENDS.
THIS WOMAN WAS ON THE PHONE
WAITING TO HEAR ABOUT HER SISTER
A TEACHER AT THE SCHOOL.
WE DO NOT KNOW TONIGHT WHAT
HAPPENED TO HER SISTER, WHETHER
OR NOT SHE'S ALIVE OR AMONG THE
DOZENS OF DEAD INSIDE THAT
BUILDING.
REPORTS INDICATE THE GUNMAN IS
NAMED ADAM PLAN ZOO, AGE 20.
SEGMENTERS SAY HE DIED INSIDE
THE SCHOOL AS WELL, APPARENTLY
COMMITTING SUICIDE AFTER
INFLICTING UNIMAGINABLE PAIN ON
SO MANY FAMILIES.
INCLUDING HIS OWN.
STATE POLICE CONFIRM THE GUNMAN
SHOT SOMEBODY ELSE ALL BEFORE
THIS AT THE SCHOOL.
SOMEBODY HE LIVED WITH.
THAT VICTIM, APPARENTLY HIS OWN
MOTHER.
FOX NEWS HAS CONFIRMED THE GUN
THAT HE USED WERE HERS.
ALL LEGALLY PURCHASED AND
REGISTERED, GLOCK AND HAND GUNS
AND A SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE.
THE WEAPONS USED TO MURDER 27
PEOPLE TODAY AND SHATTER
COUNTLESS LIVES IN CONNECTICUT.
WE HAVE TEAM FOX COVERAGE.
MOLLY LINE WITH US.
BUT WE BEGIN WITH A FOX REPORT
CHIEF CORRESPONDENT JONATHAN
HUNT WITH ME LIVE IN NEWTOWN
TONIGHT.
IT IS HARD TO IMAGINE WHAT THESE
CHILDREN WENT THROUGH TODAY.
>> IT IS THE TERROR THAT THEY
EXPERIENCE TODAY, BILL,
UNIMAGINABLE.
THE PICTURES THAT YOU SEE, THOSE
FACES FILLED WITH TEARS, THE
FACES FILLED WITH TERROR GIVE
YOU SOME IDEA.
THESE WERE TINY CHILDREN, AGES
BETWEEN FIVE AND TEN, WE WERE
TOLD BEING BROUGHT OUT OF THAT
SCHOOL IN THE MIDDLE OF A
HORRIFIC SCENE.
THEIR TERROR PERHAPS ONLY
MATCHED BY THE TERROR OF PARENTS
WHO HEARD THAT THIS SCENE WAS
UNFOLDING AND RUSHED TO THE
SCHOOL IN A DESPERATE SEARCH FOR
THEIR CHILDREN.
LISTEN.
>> DOESN'T EVEN SEEM REAL.
IT JUST DOES NOT SEEM LIKE IT'S
EVEN POSSIBLE.
>> THERE IS NO WORDS.
IT'S SHEAR TERROR AND A SENSE OF
IMMEDIATE URGENCY AND TO GET TO
YOUR CHILD AND TO BE THERE TO
PROTECT THEM.
>> NOW, WE'RE TOLD THAT AS THEY
WERE BEING LED OUT, THE CHILDREN
WHO SURVIVED THIS SLAUGHTER,
WERE TOLD BY COPS AND TEACHERS
TO COVER THEIR EYES.
ONE CAN ONLY IMAGINE THEY WERE
TOLD THAT BECAUSE THEY WERE
LITERALLY STEPPING AROUND AND
OVER THE BODIES OF THEIR
CLASSMATES, BILL.
>> THERE HAS BEEN A LOT OF
CONFUSION THROUGHOUT THE DAY ON
THE FACTS OF THIS STORY.
WE'RE TRYING TO SORT THIS
THROUGH THE HOUR AND URGE OUR
VIEWERS TO BE PARENT AS WE WORK
THROUGH IT.
THERE IS A LOT OF CONFUSION
ABOUT THE SHOOTER.  WHAT CAN WE
REPORT?
>> WHAT WE'RE BEING TOLD NOW BY
U.S. OFFICIALS IS THAT THE
SHOOTER IS 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM
LANZA.
THERE WAS CONFUSION EARLIER
BECAUSE HE MAY HAVE BEEN
CARRYING HIS ELDER BROTHER, RYAN
LANZA'S I.D., HIS ELDER BROTHER
IS 24.
HE'S IN CUSTODY.
HE'S HELPING THE F.B.I. WITH
THEIR QUESTIONS, APPARENTLY
BEING VERY COOPERATIVE.
NOT A SUSPECT IN ANY WAY.
BUT THE SHOOTER, WE'RE TOLD,
THIS 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA.
ACCORDING TO RICK LEVENTHAL, WHO
HAS BEEN LEADING MUCH OF THE
REPORTING TODAY ON THIS, ADAM
LANZA WOKE THUMB MORNING AT HIS
MOTHER'S HOME, SHOT HER IN THE
FACE AND THEN CAME TO THIS
SCHOOL.
IMAGINE THE SCENE RIGHT NOW IN
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
THOUGH THE BODIES OF THE
CHILDREN, MANY OF THEM STILL
THERE, WE ARE TOLD, AND THE
DIFFICULTIES ARE CAUGHT IN
IDENTIFYING IT, THE ONLY WAY
BECAUSE THESE KIDS OBVIOUSLY
DON'T CARRY I.D., IS FOR THE
PARENTS TO ACTUALLY IDENTIFY THE
BODIES THEMSELVES.
GOVERNOR MALLOY TALKED ABOUT
THAT DIFFICULT PROCESS EARLIER
TODAY.
LISTEN.
>> OUR POLICE PERSONNEL AND
OTHERS ARE DOING THE UTMOST TO
CLEAR THIS SITUATION AS SOON AS
POSSIBLE TO RETURN THESE
CHILDREN TO THEIR PARENTS OR
THESE LOVED ONES TO THEIR FELLOW
LOVED ONES AS QUICKLY AS
POSSIBLE.
AND WE'LL WORK WITH ALL OF THE
RESIDENTS OF THIS COMMUNITY AND
CONNECTICUT TO MAKE SURE THAT WE
DO, IN FACT, GET THROUGH THIS.
>> JUST IMAGINE, BILL, THAT MANY
OF THESE PARENTS HAVE PROBABLY
ALREADY BOUGHT AND WRAPPED
CHRISTMAS PRESENTS, PUT THEM
UNDER THE TREE.
THEY'LL NEVER BE ABLE TO GIVE
THEM TO THEIR KIDS.
>> TEN OR 11 DAYS FROM NOW.
WE HAVE BEEN TOLD THAT INSIDE
THAT SCHOOL IT'S A GRISLY SCENE
AND IT'S NOT SIMPLISTIC, MEANING
THAT THERE IS A LOT OF EVIDENCE
THESE INVESTIGATORS HAVE TO GO
THROUGH.
THE MIND REELS WHEN YOU THINK
ABOUT IT.
IF YOU'RE A POLICE OFFICER
ARRIVING INSIDE THAT CLASSROOM
ST HAVE SEEN.
THERE ARE ACCOUNTS APPARENTLY
THAT AM SO OF THE FIRST
RESPONDERS ARE PRETTY BROKEN UP.
>> POLICE OFFICERS AND
FIREFIGHTERS.
THERE WAS A FIRE HOUSE VERY NEAR
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND
SOME OF THOSE FIREFIGHTERS WERE
AMONG THE FIRST TO GET THERE.
WE HEARD REPORTS, WE DID NOT SEE
IT WITH OUR OWN EYES -- BUT
UNDERSTANDABLY WERE LEAVING THE
SCHOOL IN TEARS.
THEY HAD GONE IN OBVIOUSLY,
FOUND 20 CHILDREN AMONG 26 DEAD.
IT IS OBVIOUSLY THERE WILL BE A
LOT OF COUNSELING FOR THE
CHILDREN, FOR THE PARENTS, AND
AS THE COPS SAID TODAY, FOR THE
FIRST RESPONDERS.
LISTEN.
>> THE FIRST RESPONDERS TO COME
TOGETHER, COUNSELORS, IT'S
AMAZING HOW THE IMMENSE AMOUNT
OF FAMILY THAT'S SHOWN IN FRONT
OF NEWTOWN.
EVERYONE IS COMING TOGETHER,
SUPPORTING EVERYONE, WORKING
TOGETHER, TRYING TO ANSWER ALL
THE QUESTIONS AS TO HOW AND WHY
THIS OCCURRED AND TRYING TO LEND
SUPPORT TO ALL THE PEOPLE
INVOLVED, INCLUDING THE VICTIMS.
>> ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE, BILL, I
THINK ULTIMATELY TO EVEN PUT
INTO WORDS THE AMOUNT OF PAIN
BEING FELT IN THIS COMMUNITY.
>> I'VE BEEN WITH YOU THROUGHOUT
THE DAY AND TERRIFIC WORK UNDER
TRYING CIRCUMSTANCES AND MANY IN
THE TOWN, YOU REALLY FEEL FOR
WHAT THEY'RE GOING THROUGH.
WE SHOULD GET BRIEFING FROM THE
SHERIFF'S DEPARTMENT THIS HOUR.
WHEN THAT HAPPENS, WE'LL BRING
IT YOU WANT TO INVESTIGATORS SAY
THEY FOUND THE SUSPECT'S MOTHER
DEAD INSIDE HER HOME.
NOT FAR FROM THE SCHOOL, ABOUT
TEN MILES.
THAT'S WHAT FEDERAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT SOURCES ARE TELLING
US TONIGHT.
LOCAL POLICE HAVE NOT YET
CONFIRMED A LOT OF THIS, BUT
MOLLY LINE IS WORKING THAT PART
OF THE STORY.
SHE IS OUTSIDE THE MOTHER'S HOME
HERE IN NEARBY NEWTOWN.
WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED INSIDE THAT HOUSE THAT
WAS OWNED BY NANCY LANZA?
MOLLY, GOOD EVENING TO YOU.
>> BILL, MUCH OF THE INFORMATION
HAS BEEN GATHERED FROM
AUTHORITIES HERE IN CONNECTICUT
AT THE FEDERAL LEVEL AND FROM
RICK LEVENTHAL WHO SPENT MUCH OF
THE DAY WITH THE AUTHORITIES
ATTENDING THOSE PRESS
CONFERENCES AND HE'LL HAVE A LOT
MORE DETAIL INFORMATION TO COME
IN THIS HOUR.
BUT WHAT WE KNOW ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED THIS MORNING IS THAT
ADAM LANZA GOT UP, SHOT HIS
MOTHER, NANCY LANZA, IN THE
FACE, WHO IS A TEACHER AT THE
SCHOOL WHERE MUCH OF THE
HORRIFIC ACTIVITIES HAPPENED
TODAY.
HE THEN GATHERED HER WEAPONS,
REGISTERED WEAPONS IN HER NAME,
TWO HAND GUN AND A RIFLE, GOT IN
HER CAR AND DROVE TO THE SCHOOL.
THOSE ARE THE ACTIVITIES  THAT
HAPPENED HERE IN THE
NEIGHBORHOOD THAT WE KNOW ABOUT.
A HORRIBLE CIRCUMSTANCE,
PARTICULARLY WHEN YOU LOOK DOWN
A STREET, UPPER CLASS HOMES,
BEAUTIFUL CHRISTMAS DECORATIONS.
HORRIFIC ACTIVITY, NOTHING WOULD
HAVE BEEN EXPECTED LIKE THIS.
>> MOLLY, YOU HAD A CHANCE TO
SPEAK TO A LOT OF PEOPLE IN THE
SMALL TOWN.
WHAT ARE THEY TELLING YOU ABOUT
HOW THEY'RE TRYING TO PROCESS
AND UNDERSTAND THIS?
>> YOU KNOW, IT WAS AN EMOTIONAL
EXPERIENCE ALL ACROSS THE
COMMUNITY TODAY, PARTICULARLY
WHEN NOBODY HAD ANY IDEA WHAT
WAS GOING ON, PARTICULARLY WHEN
TEXT MESSAGES WERE COMING TO
PARENTS' PHONES.
WE SPOKE TO A WOMAN WHO WORKED
AT A CAFE.
THIS IS A SMALL TOWN WITH
INDEPENDENTLY OWNED BUSINESSES
LINING THE STREETS AND SHE SAID
THERE WERE A NUMBER OF MOTHERS
AT THE SCHOOL GETTING THE PHONE
CALLS AND TEXT MESSAGES,
ABSOLUTELY HORRIFYING, RUNNING
FROM HER STORE AND HER FEAR IS
THAT SHE WILL KNOW SOME OF THOSE
CHILDREN THAT WERE KILLED TODAY.
WE HAD A CHANCE TO SPEAK WITH A
WOMAN WHO OWNS A HAIR CUTTING
PLACE FOR KIDS, SPECIFICALLY FOR
CHILDREN.
SHE SAYS FOR MANY OF THE
VICTIMS, SHE SUSPECTS SHE MAY
HAVE GIVEN THEM THEIR FIRST HAIR
CUT AND THEIR SECOND HAIR CUT
AND THIRD HAIR CUT.
THIS IS A VERY SMALL COMMUNITY
WITH SMALL BUSINESSES LINING THE
STREETS.
REALLY THE TYPE OF PLACE WHERE
EVERYONE KNOWS EVERYONE ELSE AND
THERE IS A WAIT AND SEE NOW TO
FIND OUT WHO AMONG THEM ARE
AMONG THE VICTIMS.
BILL.
>> INDEED THERE IS.
THANK YOU.
MOLLY LINE, ABOUT TEN MILES FROM
OUR LOCATION RIGHT NEAR THE
SCHOOL HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THANK YOU FOR THAT REPORT.
I MET A YOUNG GIRL EARLIER
TODAY.
SHE SAID IT'S HER BIRTHDAY
SHE TURNED 11 YEARS OLD AND SHE
ASKED HER MOTHER IF THIS WILL BE
HER OWN 9-11.
THERE IS SO MUCH CONFUSION, AS
YOU CAN IMAGINE, AS PEOPLE SORT
THROUGH THIS.
WE ARE LEARNING, BY THE WAY,
MORE TONIGHT ABOUT THE FAMILY OF
THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER.
HARRIS FAULKNER SPOKE WITH A
SOURCE CLOSE TO THEM.
SHE'S LIVE IN OUR STUDIOS IN NEW
YORK AND GOOD EVENING TO YOU.
>> GOOD EVENING.
AS WE'VE BEEN SAYING FOR THE
FIRST THREE HOURS OF REPORTING
ON THIS STORY TODAY, WE WERE
BEING TOLD BY AUTHORITIES A MAN
IN HIS 20S NAMED RYAN LANZA WAS
THE SHOOTER AND WAS DEAD.
TONIGHT, OF COURSE, WE KNOW AND
HAVE TOLD YOU HIS YOUNGER
BROTHER, ADAM, IS THE ONE WHO IS
DEAD, SUSPECTED OF CARRYING OUT
THE MASSACRE, WEARING HIS OLDER
BROTHER'S IDENTIFICATION.
BUT WE ALSO KNOW THAT ORIGINAL
SUSPECT, RYAN LANZA, HAS BEEN IN
CUSTODY FOR MUCH OF THE DEREK
BEING QUESTIONED IN HOBOKEN, NEW
JERSEY.
OFFICIALS BELIEVE RYAN LANZA IS
COOPERATING AND NOT BELIEVED TO
HAVE BEEN INVOLVED IN THE
RAMPAGE.
FOX NEWS HAS CONFIRMED RYAN
LANZA HAS A FACEBOOK PAGE.
IT IS ACTIVE.
WE'RE NOT SHOWING IT HERE.
BUT IT LISTS HIM FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AND LIVING IN
HOBOKEN.
IT CAUGHT OUR ATTENTION TODAY
WHEN HE OR SOMEONE ELSE ON HIS
BEHALF BEGAN LEAVING MESSAGES
ON-LINE VIA TWITTER ABOUT RYAN
LANZA NOT BEING THE SHOOTER AND
SAYING HIS FACEBOOK PAGE SHOWED
A MAN WHO HAD NOT DONE THE
HORRIBLE THING IN CONNECTICUT.
AT THE SAME TIME, A SOURCE
TELLING ME RYAN WAS PART OF A
FAMILY THAT LIVED A VERY QUIET
EXISTENCE.
THE DAD OFTEN VISITED RYAN LANZA
WHEN HE WAS ENROLLED AT QUINN
PEE YACK UNIVERSITY AND THE TWO
APPEARED TO HAVE A GOOD
RELATIONSHIP.
BUT THAT RYAN TALKED SO LITTLE
ABOUT HIS FAMILY THAT EVEN THOSE
PEOPLE WHO KNEW HIM FOR YEARS
KNEW VERY FEW DETAILS ABOUT
THEM.
NOT ONE PICTURE OF HIS FAMILY
INSIDE HIS COLLEGE ROOM.
NO MENTION OF HIS BROTHER, ADAM.
IT SEEMED AS THOUGH RYAN'S
PARENTS WERE DIVORCED, BUT FEW
PEOPLE WERE SURE ABOUT THAT.
IN FACT, I CAN SAY THAT THEY ARE
DIVORCED.
THE DAD, PETER LANZA, LIVES NOT
FAR FROM THE SCENE IN
CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE TOLD HE'S STILL TALKING
WITH F.B.I. AGENTS, BUT NOT
SUSPECTED OF HAVING ANY ROLE IN
WHAT PLAYED OUT TODAY.
BILL?
>> HAIR I THANK YOU FOR THAT.
WE'LL BE IN TOUCH LATER THIS
HOUR.
HARRIS FAULKNER REPORT NOT
GUILTY NEW YORK.
AVERAGE CLASS SIZE IN THIS
SCHOOL DISTRICT FOR KIDS IN
KINDERGARTEN, 17.
THE LAST SERIOUS CRIME REPORTED
IN THIS TOWN?
TWO YEARS AGO.
2010.
MUCH MORE AHEAD.
MASSACRE AT SANDY HOOK,
INCLUDING ALL THIS DEVELOPING
INFORMATION ABOUT THE SUSPECT
AND CERTAINLY ABOUT THE VICTIMS
TONIGHT.
A LIVE LOOK OUTSIDE SAINT ROSE
CHURCH IN NEWTOWN WHERE MEMBERS
OF THIS COMMUNITY ARE GATHERING
FOR A MEMORIAL SERVICE, JUST
GETTING UNDERWAY TO REMEMBER THE
INNOCENT VICTIMS.
PLUS A VISIBLY SHAKEN PRESIDENT
OBAMA ADDRESSING THE NATION A
FEW HOURS AGO.
WE WILL SHARE THAT WITH YOU AS
WELL, COMING UP TONIGHT ON THE
FOX REPORT
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Sharable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>> Bill: OUR COVERAGE CONTINUES
LIVE.
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL MASSACRE
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
I'M BILL HEMMER, GOOD EVENING
AGAIN.
A SHOOTER ENTERED A SCHOOL
EARLIER TODAY SHOOTING TO DEATH
20 CHILDREN, SIX ADULTS.
ALEXIS SAYS SHE WAS IN A
CLASSROOM WHEN POLICE BURST IN
AND TOLD EVERYONE TO HIDE IN A
CORNER.
NOW WHAT HAPPENED WITH HER
DAUGHTER AND GOOD EVENING TO
YOU.
WOW.
WHAT A DAY THIS MUST BE.
>> UNBELIEVABLE DAY.
SHE'S HOLDING UP AND SHE'S BEEN
A TROOPER.
WE'RE DOING A LOT OF TALKING AND
A LOT OF COMMUNICATING AND A LOT
OF EXTRA HUGS AND KISS.
>> Bill: HOW DO YOU COMMUNICATE
WITH HER NOW, LYNN?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
>> WE'RE HONEST WITH HER AND SHE
DIDN'T KNOW THAT THE PRINCIPAL
HAD BEEN KILLED AND SO SHE HAD
HEARD THAT ON THE NEWS.
I SAT DOWN NEXT TO HER AND
EXPLAINED TO HER WHAT HAD
HAPPENED AND THE MAN THAT DID
ALL OF THIS IS NO LONGER HERE.
WE TALKED A LOT ABOUT FEELINGS
AND TALKED A LOT ABOUT HOW ARE
YOU DOING AND IS THERE ANYTHING
YOU WOULD LIKE OR WHAT DO YOU
WANT TO TALK ABOUT, OR -- JUST
IN GENERAL, JUST HOW ARE YOU AS
A PERSON?
SHE'S EIGHT.
SHE'S NOT TWO.
SO THERE IS, UNFORTUNATELY, YOU
CAN'T HIDE THINGS FROM CHILDREN
AT THIS AGE.
SO WE'RE JUST IN CONSTANT
COMMUNICATION WITH HER TO KIND
OF CHECK IN AND SAY, ARE YOU
DOING OKAY?
OR WHAT ARE YOU THINKING ABOUT?
ARE YOU SAD?
HER AND I JOURNAL BACK AND FORTH
VERY OFTEN.
SO WE WILL CONTINUE TO DO THIS.
AND IT'S BEEN A GREAT TOOL FOR
THE TWO OF US AND WE'LL WRITE
DIFFERENT THINGS THAT HAPPENED
DURING THE DAY OR IF WE'RE
FEELING HAPPY OR SAD OR
SOMETHING IS BOTHERING US.
SO THIS WILL BE A PHENOMENAL
TOOL THAT WE WILL HAVE GOING
FORWARD.
BUT SHE'S BEEN OPEN AND HONEST
AND SHE IS SAD AND SO SHE'S JUST
LIKE MAMA, ARE YOU OKAY?
I'M LIKE, HONEY, I'M MORE THAN
OKAY.
I'M JUST WORRIED FOR YOU.
I'M WORRIED FOR THEIR FRIENDS,
FOR OUR FRIENDS AT THE SCHOOL
AND EVERYBODY THAT WE'VE BEEN IN
CONTACT WITH OVER THE YEARS.
>> Bill: LYNN, YOU SOUND LIKE A
TERRIFIC MOTHER AND ALEXIS IS
LUCKY TO HAVE YOU.
I KNOW TONIGHT YOU FEEL VERY
LUCKY TO HAVE HER.
THANK YOU FOR SHARING PART OF
YOUR STORY WITH US TODAY.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Bill: SO MANY PEOPLE ACROSS
THIS COUNTRY REALLY, THEIR
PRAYERS ARE IN YOUR CORNER.
THEY'RE PULLING FOR YOU.
>> WE APPRECIATE EVERYTHING.
THANK YOU.
>> Bill: YOU BET.
OUR BEST TO ALEXIS.
OKAY?
B.
>> YOU BET.
>> Bill: ALL RIGHT.
MORE FROM CONNECTICUT IN A
MOMENT HERE.
ALSO WE'RE GOING TO GET A BIT
MORE FROM WASHINGTON, D.C. AS
OFFICIALS, I THE
PRESIDENT, EXPRESSED THEIR SHOCK
AND SADNESS TODAY AS OUR
COVERAGE CONTINUES.
WE ARE LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, TONIGHT ON A DAY
THAT --
>> Bill: NOW THE SCENE INSIDE OF
SAINT ROSE, A LOCAL CHURCH HERE
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, A VIGIL
BEGAN ABOUT 23 MINUTES AGO.
7:00  O'CLOCK LOCAL TIME AS THAT
SERVICE CONTINUES.
THERE IS A CHURCH DOWN THE ROAD,
ST. JOHN EPISCOPAL CHURCH.
THERE IS A SIGN OUTSIDE THAT
SAYS, HEALING PRAYER TODAY AT
ALL THE CHURCHES IN THIS
COMMUNITY, INCLUDING THIS ONE AT
SAINT ROSE, WE WATCH AND PULL
FOR THE FOLKS WHO ARE GATHERED
HERE TONIGHT.
>> I HAVEN'T THE WORDS THAT
MAKES THE PAIN OF WHAT HAPPENED
TODAY EASY TO BEAR.
I'M HEART BROKEN AS I KNOW ALL
OF YOU ARE.
BUT NOTHING HURTS MORE THAN THE
LOSS OF INNOCENCE, BUT NO MORE
SO WITH THOSE THAT ARE LEFT.
I'M HEART BROKEN AND I KNOW MANY
OF YOU SHARE MY GRIEF.
I HAVE A SIMPLE PRAYER, I TURN
TO GOD IN TIMES LIKE THIS.
MY PRAYER IS VERY SIMPLE.
SHOW ME AND SHOW US THE WAY TO
WRAP OUR ARMS AROUND THOSE
FAMILIES THAT HAVE BEEN SO
AFFECTED BY THIS EVENT.
SHOW US HOW WE CAN HEAL AND HOW
WE CAN HELP THEM HEAL.
BY GREAT FAITH AND LOVE FOR THIS
COMMUNITY.
I KNOW WE ARE A GOOD AND GENTLE
PLACE.
WE WILL SOMEHOW MANAGE TO GET
THROUGH THIS HORRIBLE EVENT
BURKS WE NEED TO DO IT TOGETHER
AND WE NEED TO WRAP OUR ARMS AND
LOVING SUPPORT AROUND THOSE
FAMILIES WHO HAVE LOST A CHILD.
I THANK YOU ALL FOR BEING HERE.
I KNEW THAT WE WOULD.
>> Bill: THIS IS ONLY THE
BEGINNING.
ONLY THE BEGINNING FOR A VERY
LONG HEALING PROCESS, ONLY TEN
HOURS INTO THIS HORRIFIC STORY
HERE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
I MENTIONED ST. JOHN EPISCOPAL
CHURCH,  WHICH IS DOWN THE ROAD
FROM HERE.
IT IS OPEN.
THE DOORS ARE OPEN OF THE THE
LIGHTS ARE ON AND THE SIGN
OUTSIDE SAYS HEALING PRAYER
TODAY.
AS I MENTIONED, THE HEALING IS
JUST UNDERWAY.
PRESIDENT OBAMA FIGHTING BACK
TEARS, SPEAKING TO THE NATION
FROM THE WHITE HOUSE ABOUT THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
A GUNMAN KILLING 26 PEOPLE,
INCLUDING 20 YOUNG CHILDREN.
THE PRESIDENT SAYING HE REACTED
TO THIS NEWS NOT AS A PRESIDENT,
BUT AS A PARENT.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF FIVE AND TEN YEARS
OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM, BIRTHDAYS,
GRADUATIONS, WEDDINGS, KIDS OF
THEIR OWN.
>> Bill: THERE IS A LOT OF THAT
EMOTION THROUGHOUT THE COUNTRY
TONIGHT.
THE PRESIDENT ORDERING FLAGS AT
THE WHITE HOUSE, ALL GOVERNMENT
BUILDINGS AND MILITARY BASES TO
FLY AT HALF-STAFF FOR THE NEXT
FEW DAYS.
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER
TWEETING EARLIER HE'S DOING THE
SAME WITH THE CAPITOL IN TRIBUTE
TO THE VICTIMS AND THEIR
FAMILIES.
HE ADDED THE HASH TAG, PRAY FOR
NEWTOWN.
ED HENRY JOINS US LIVE AT THE
WHITE HOUSE TONIGHT.
THE PRESIDENT MADE IT CLEAR, THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT STANDS BY
THIS TOWN IN CONNECTICUT.
>> NO DOUBT ABOUT IT.
GOOD EVENING, BILL.
YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
YOU SOUGHT THE RAW EMOTION FROM
THE PRESIDENT.
I WAS SITTING A FEW FEET AWAY
FROM JAY CARNEY, THE WHITE HOUSE
SPOKESMAN.
HE TOOK HIS EYEGLASSES OFF AT
ONE POINT, WAS WIPING HIS EYES
AS THE PRESIDENT SPOKE.
YOU DON'T NORMALLY SEE THAT,
OBVIOUSLY, AROUND HERE AT THE
WHITE HOUSE WHEN THEY'VE BEEN
GOING THROUGH THE FISCAL CLIFF
AND ALL THESE OTHER MAJOR
ISSUES.
ALL THAT IS ON THE SIDE LINES
NOW, AT LEAST FOR A FEW DAYS.
BOTTOM LINE, YOU MENTIONED THE
FLAGS LOWERED TO HALF-STAFF
HERE.
THEY HAVE TO GO FORWARD WITH THE
BUSINESS OF GOVERNMENT, THOUGH,
BECAUSE AS YOU ALSO NOTED, THE
PRESIDENT CALLED THE CONNECTICUT
GOVERNOR TODAY.
HE HAVE ALSO CALLED THE F.B.I.
DIRECTOR, ROBERT MULLER, AND
PLEDGED ALL FEDERAL RESOURCES TO
ASSIST IN THIS INVESTIGATION,
HELP STATE AND LOCAL
AUTHORITIES.
AS I MENTIONED IN TERMS OF THE
FISCAL CLIFF, THE PRESIDENT WAS
SUPPOSED TO TRAVEL TO MAINE NEXT
WEDNESDAY.
PRESSURE REPUBLICANS OUT ON THE
ROAD ABOUT GETTING A FISCAL
CLIFF DEAL.
I'M TOLD THAT TRIP HAS BEEN
CANCELED.
THEY MAY OBVIOUSLY HAVE TO BE
DEALING WITH A MEMORIAL SERVICE
NEXT WEEK, BILL.
>> Bill: ED, THERE WAS A MENTION
TODAY WHERE THE PRESIDENT SEEMED
TO MAKE NEWS ON GUN CONTROL.
WHAT WAS SAID THERE?
>> HE DID.
EARLIER WHEN THERE HAD BEEN
OTHER TRAGEDIES, WHETHER IT BE
TUCSON OR AURORA, THE PRESIDENT
SPOKE GENERALLY ABOUT A NATIONAL
CONVERSATION ON THIS ISSUE, BUT
HAD NOT FOLLOWED UP WITH ACTION.
TODAY HE SUGGESTED VERY CLEARLY
THAT IN A SECOND TERM, THAT MAY
CHANGE.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> THESE NEIGHBORHOODS ARE OUR
NEIGHBORHOODS AND THESE CHILDREN
ARE OUR CHILDREN.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO COME
TOGETHER AND TAKE MEANINGFUL
ACTION TO PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS, REGARDLESS OF THE
POLITICS.
>> Bill: CAPTAIN MARK KELLY, THE
HUSBAND OF FORMER CONGRESSWOMAN
GABBY GIFFORDS, WHO IS STILL
RECOVERING FROM THAT SHOOTING IN
TUCSON, HE TODAY SAID THAT SHE
SENDS HER PRAYERS FROM TUCSON TO
THE PEOPLE THERE WHERE YOU ARE
IN CONNECTICUT AND CAPTAIN KELLY
ADDED THAT HE BELIEVES A
MEANINGFUL DISCUSSION OF THOSE
GUN LAWS IS LONG OVERDUE.
BILL.
>> Bill: THANK YOU.
ED HENRY ON THE NORTH LAWN AT
THE WHITE HOUSE.
WE'RE WATCHING THIS MEMORIAL
HERE IN NEWTOWN.
THE GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT HAS
JUST GONE TO THE PULPIT THERE.
LET'S DROP IN HERE FOR A QUICK
MOMENT.
>> MAY GOD BLESS OUR CHILDREN
WHO ARE WITH US TODAY AND THOSE
WHO WERE TAKEN AWAY.
MY GOD BLESS THE ADULTS WHO LOST
THEIR LIVES TODAY.
THANK YOU.
>> Bill: THIS IS SMALL TOWN
AMERICA, BEAUTIFUL ROLLING
HILLS, ONLY 90 MINUTES NORTH OF
NEW YORK CITY.
NEIGHBORS KNOW NEIGHBORS AND
FAMILIES KNOW FAMILIES AND
THEY'RE GOING TO NEED EACH AND
EVERY ONE TO GET THROUGH THIS.
WE HAVE LIVE COVERAGE WHERE
SHORTLY AFTER TODAY'S SHOOTING,
POLICE TOOK THE SUSPECT'S
BROTHER OUT IN HANDCUFFS.
WHAT HAPPENED THERE?
A LIVE LOOK INSIDE OF SAINT ROSE
CHURCH.
YOU WERE JUST WATCHING WHERE
MEMBERS OF THE COMMUNITY GATHER
FOR THE FIRST OF MANY MEMORIAL
SERVICES.
THAT'S COMING UP AS WE APPROACH
THE BOTTOM OF THE HOUR AND THE
TOP OF THE NEWS THAT ON THIS DAY
IS SO, SO SAD.
>> YOU SPEAK ELOQUENTLY
IN COMMUNITY N EMBRACING EACH
OTHER, NOT JUST BY YOUR PHYSICAL
PRESENCE, BUT BY ALL OF YOUR
EMOTIONS AND SENDING A MESSAGE
TO ALL OF AMERICA, AND BELIEVE
ME, THE HEARTS AND PRAYERS OF
AMERICA ARE WITH YOU TONIGHT.
THANK YOU FOR BEING HERE
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN IT COMES TO
THE FINANCIAL OBSTACLES
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAN
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
MAKE A WISH!
I WISH WE COULD
LIE HERE FOREVER.
I WISH THIS TEST DRIVE WAS OVER,
SO WE COULD HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
TEST DRIVE!
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A JETTA.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN,
$0 DUE AT SIGNING, $0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
12346 BACK LIVE NOW IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, I'M BILL HEMMER IN
FOR SHEPARD SMITH.
POLICE SAY A MAN WALKED INTO
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
KILLING 26 PEOPLE, 20 OF THEM
KINDERGARTEN CHILDREN.
>> EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY
TODAY.
AND IT'S TOO EARLY TO SPEAK OF
RECOVERY, BUT EACH PARENT, EACH
SIBLING, EACH MEMBER OF THE
FAMILY HAS TO UNDERSTAND THAT
CONNECTICUT, WE'RE ALL IN THIS
TOGETHER, WILL DO WHATEVER WE
CAN TO OVERCOME THIS EVENT.
WE WILL GET THROUGH IT.
>> Bill: WE ARE PIECING THE
STORY TOGETHER LITERALLY AS WE
MOVE THROUGHOUT THE HOUR
TONIGHT.
HERE IS WHAT WE KNOW.
THE SHOOTER, IDENTIFIED AS
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA.
SOURCES SAY HE KILLED HIS OWN
MOTHER IN HER HOME WHERE HE
LIVED BEFORE COMMITTING MASS
MURDER AT THAT ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
RICK LEVENTHAL LIVE AT THE SPOT
WHERE POLICE HAVE BEEN UPDATING
US THROUGHOUT THE DAY AND WE
EXPECT A BRIEFING AGAIN SOMETIME
LATER TONIGHT.
YOU HAVE A LOT OF INFORMATION.
WHAT MORE TOO WE KNOW ABOUT HOW
THIS UNFOLDED TONIGHT?
GOOD EVENING.
>> GOOD EVENING, BILL.
AS YOU MENTIONED, ACCORDING TO
SOURCES, ADAM LANZA WOKE UP THIS
MORNING IN HIS MOTHER'S HOME IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, SHOT HER,
APPARENTLY IN THE FACE WITH ONE
OF THREE WEAPONS AND HE THEN
TOOK TO THE SCHOOL, DROVE THERE
IN HIS MOTHER'S CAR.
HIS MOTHER APPARENTLY WORKED AT
THE SCHOOL.
SOME ARE SAYING SHE MAY HAVE
BEEN A SUBSTITUTE THERE.
IN ANY EHAVE NOT, ADAM LANZA,
ACCORDING TO SOURCES, WALKED
INTO THE SCHOOL AND BEGAN
SHOOTING INNOCENT CHILDREN AND
INNOCENT ADULTS.
AS YOU MENTIONED, THERE ARE 20
CONFIRMED CHILDREN DEAD AND SIX
ADULTS.
ADAM LANZA THEN APPARENTLY
KILLED HIMSELF WITH ONE OF THOSE
THREE GUNS.
HE USED A GLOCK, SIX HOUR AND
WHAT'S DESCRIBED AS AN M 4 TYPE
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE.
THIS SHOOTING TRANSPIRED JUST
AFTER 9:30 IN THE MORNING.
POLICE, LOCAL POLICE WERE
CALLED.
THEY ARRIVED AT THE SCENE.
IMMEDIATELY CALLED STATE POLICE
AND AS OFFICERS ARRIVED, THEY
WENT RIGHT INSIDE THAT SCHOOL
SEARCHING FOR STUDENTS AND
TEACHERS TO BRING TO SAFETY.
THEY ALL -- THEY DID GET OUT,
EVERYONE ELSE WHO HADN'T BEEN
HIT BY THIS GUNMAN, GOT OUT OF
THE SCHOOL.
THEY WERE TAKEN TO A NEARBY FIRE
HOUSE,  WHICH WAS SET UP AS A
STAGING AREA.
THEN AS FRANTIC PARENTS WHO
HEARD ABOUT THE SHOOTING WERE
ARRIVING ON SCENE, THOSE PARENTS
WERE REUNITED WITH THEIR
CHILDREN AT THAT FIRE HOUSE.
THEN WERE ABLE TO GO HOME.
BILL, YOU CAN IMAGINE THE TERROR
MANY OF THESE KIDS HEARD THE GUN
FIRE, SOME OF THEM SAW THE
GUNMAN.
SOME KIDS APPARENTLY SAW THIS
GUNMAN COME INTO THEIR CLASS AND
SHOOT THEIR TEACHER AND RAN OUT
AND MANAGED TO GET OUT.
UNFORTUNATELY, 20 INNOCENT
CHILDREN AND SIX OTHER ADULTS
DID NOT.
>> Bill: WE ARE TOLD IN A MANY
OF THE CHILDREN WERE TOLD TO
CLOSE THEIR EYES AND RUN AND
ONCE THEY GET OUTSIDE, TO RUN
TOWARD THE FIRE HOUSE, WHICH
SEEING THE SCHOOL AND THE FIRE
HOUSE AND THE ROAD THAT LEADS TO
IT.
THIS IS A PICTURESQUE PLACE TO
SEND YOUR KIDS TO SCHOOL.
A SMALL COMMUNITY WITH A SMALL
SCHOOL BUILDING, JUST ABOUT ONE
BUILDING COMPRISES THE ENTIRE
CAMPUS WITH A BASEBALL FIELD
BEHIND IT.
NOW, RICK, HERE IS WHAT WE'RE
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT.
THIS GUNMAN, WHO IS NOW DEAD,
APPARENTLY HAS AT LEAST ONE
BROTHER.
HE ALLEGEDLY SHOT HIS MOM IN THE
FACE.
SHE'S DEAD.
BUT HE HAS A FATHER AS WELL.
WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT THE
MEMBERS OF THE FAMILY AND
WHETHER OR NOT THEY ARE GIVING
INFORMATION TONIGHT?
>> MY UNDERSTANDING IS THAT THE
FATHER IS WITH FEDERAL
AUTHORITIES IN NEW JERSEY AND IS
BEING QUESTIONED BY THE F.B.I.
AND OTHER AUTHORITIES IN NEW
JERSEY, ALONG WITH THE BROTHER,
RYAN LANZA, WHO EARLIER TODAY
WAS BEING IDENTIFIED AS THE
SHOOTER.
APPARENTLY THERE WAS CONFUSION
BECAUSE ADAM LANZA, MAY HAVE
BEEN CARRYING HIS BROTHER'S I.D
THAT MAY HAVE LED THEM TO THE
BROTHER'S APARTMENT IN HOBOKEN.
THAT'S WHERE THEY FOUND THE
BROTHER, RYAN, QUESTIONED HIM.
I'M TOLD HE IS BEING
COOPERATIVE.
HIS GIRLFRIEND BEING COOPERATIVE
AS WELL.
AND THE FATHER HAS BEEN
DESCRIBED AS BEING COOPERATIVE,
TOO.
THERE ARE SOME REPORTS THAT THE
FAMILY HASN'T REALLY SPOKEN WITH
ADAM MUCH LATELY.
WE CAN'T CONFIRM THAT.
WHAT I CAN TELL YOU IS THAT THE
FATHER AND THE BROTHER ARE BEING
QUESTIONED BY THE F.B.I
ANY INSIGHT THEY MAY BE ABLE TO
GIVE TO ADAM'S MENTAL STATE
OBVIOUSLY WOULD BE VALUABLE IN
THIS INVESTIGATION.
BILL.
>> Bill: YEAH.
ABSOLUTELY CRITICAL.
YOU'RE RIGHT ABOUT THAT.
YOU HAVE TO THINK THAT
INVESTIGATORS GO IMMEDIATELY TO
THE RELATIONSHIP THAT THIS
KILLER HA HAD WITH HIS MOM.
IS THERE ANY SIGN THAT ANYONE
HAS TALKED ABOUT THAT MAY HAVE
SPARKED THIS RAMPAGE?
>> NO IDEA.
NONE WHATSOEVER.
AND WHEN I WAS TALKING TO ONE OF
MY SOURCES, A FEDERAL AGENT WHO
HAS SEEN IT ALL AND DONE SO MUCH
IN THE FIELD OF LAW ENFORCEMENT,
HE WAS AS STUNNED AS WE ALL ARE
AT THE WAY THESE EVENTS
UNFOLDED.
STUNNED THAT NOT ONLY THIS YOUNG
MAN WHO SHOOT AND KILL HIS OWN
MOTHER IN HER OWN HOME, BUT THEN
MORE STUNNED THAT HE WOULD THEN
GO THE SCHOOL AND OPEN FIRE.
HIS MOTHER WASN'T THERE.
HIS MOTHER WAS HOME.
HE WENT TO THE SCHOOL AND KILLED
THOSE PEOPLE, ACCORDING TO
AUTHORITIES AND IT'S JUST, AT
THIS POINT, NO EXPLANATION WHY.
>> Bill: RICK, THANK YOU.
RICK LEVENTHAL HAS BEEN ON SCENE
ALL DAY.
THE NEWS BROKE AROUND 9:30 IN
THE MORNING AND ABOUT AN HOUR
LATER WHEN ALL THE DETAILS
STARTED TO UNFOLD, IT JUST GOT
WORSE EVERY TIME A REPORT CAME
OUT AND HERE WE ARE TONIGHT
TRYING TO PIECE THIS TOGETHER.
POLICE IN HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY,
SAY THAT THEY ARE TALKING AND
QUESTIONING THE SUSPECTED
GUNMAN'S BROTHER, AS RICK WAS
TALKING ABOUT.
AND TWO PEOPLE WHO MIGHT BE HIS
ROOMMATES IN NEW JERSEY.
HOBOKEN RIGHT ACROSS THE HUDSON
RIVER FROM MANHATTAN IN NEW YORK
CITY.
YOU MIGHT REMEMBER SEEING
PICTURES OF IT UNDER WATER AFTER
SUPER STORM SANDY.
ANNA KOOIMAN IS LIVE IN HOBOKEN.
WHAT ARE YOU FIGURING OUT ABOUT
THE SCENE AND WHAT IT'S LIKE
BEHIND YOU THERE?
>> BILL, YES, WE'RE PIECING
THINGS TOGETHER JUST AS YOU ARE.
THE BUILDING BEHIND US
APPARENTLY, THE APARTMENT HOME
OF THE BROTHER OF THE SHOOTER,
24-YEAR-OLD RYAN LANZA, AS WELL
AS TWO OTHER PEOPLE.
THE BUILDING IS STILL ROPED OFF
WITH POLICE TAPE.
WE GOT ON THE SCENE ABOUT 4:30
THIS AFTERNOON AND WE COUNTED
ABOUT TEN F.B.I. AGENTS AND
HOBOKEN POLICE HERE.
THEY DID BEGIN WRAPPING THINGS
UP SHORTLY AFTER.
BUT EARLIER TODAY, A VERY
DIFFERENT SCENE.
CHAOS AND CONFUSION,  WHICH MAY
HAVE BEEN SPARKED BY A BIT OF
INFORMATION WE RECEIVED FROM A
RELIABLE FEDERAL SOURCE THAT
RYAN LANZA'S I.D. ENDED UP ON
ADAM LANZA.
THAT FEDERAL SOURCE ALSO TELLING
US THAT EARLIER THIS AFTERNOON
WHEN RYAN LANZA PULLED UP TO
THIS APARTMENT BUILDING WITH HIS
GIRLFRIEND, HE NOTICED POLICE
SURROUNDING IT.
THAT'S WHEN HE WAS CUFFED AND
TAKEN AWAY APPARENTLY.
HE AND HIS GIRLFRIEND BOTH
SPEAKING WITH THE F.B.I. AND
ALSO COOPERATING WITH THEM.
THERE HAD BEEN REPORTS THAT THE
GIRLFRIEND WAS MISSING.
THAT APPARENTLY NOT THE CASE.
ALSO SOME PRELIMINARY REPORTS
THAT SOMEBODY WAS DEAD INSIDE
THIS BUILDING.
THAT NOT THE CASE, FROM
EVERYTHING THAT WE'RE HEARING.
WE'VE EVEN HEARD IT WAS POSSIBLY
THE FATHER.
AGAIN, AS RICK LEVENTHAL
MENTIONED, THAT FEDERAL SOURCE
TELLING US THAT THE FATHER IS
SPEAKING WITH THE F.B.I. HERE IN
NEW JERSEY, BILL.
>> Bill: YOU CAN IMAGINE, TOO,
WE'RE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHAT
IS FACT AND WHAT IS FRANKLY NOT
FACTS.
HOBOKEN A CROWDED COMMUNITY AND
THERE ARE A LOT OF NEIGHBORS
THERE.
HOW ARE THEY REACT TO GO WHAT
THEY SAW AT THAT SCENE TODAY?
>> THEY WATCHED IT UNFOLD JUST
LIKE THE REST OF US DID AND WHEN
THE FOCUS SHIFTED EVER SO
SLIGHTLY TO HOBOKEN, OF COURSE,
THEY BECAME EVEN MORE CONCERNED.
SOME PARENTS TELLING US THE
DAYCARE IN THE AREA WAS ON
LOCKDOWN.
THEY WERE GETTING E-MAILS ABOUT
THAT. LET'S TAKE LISTEN.
>> JUST RIPS THROUGH YOU.
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
YOU DON'T EXPECT ON A FRIDAY
AFTERNOON AT 2:00 O'CLOCK THAT
THE JERSEY CITY BOMB SQUAD WOULD
BE RUNNING THROUGH YOUR HALLS.
YOU THINK YOUR FAMILY IS HAVING
A NORMAL DAY OFF AFTERNOON AND
PLAYING WITH HIS TRUCKS AND
BEING WHO HE IS AND HE HAS TO
DEAL WITH THIS.
>> BILL, RESIDENTS IN HOBOKEN
AND CONNECTICUT REALLY ACROSS
AMERICA, HUGGING THEIR CHILDREN
A LITTLE TIGHTER TONIGHT.
>> Bill: INDEED THEY ARE.
THANK YOU.
ANNA KOOIMAN IS ON DUTY IN
HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY, FOLLOWING
THAT ASPECT OF THE STORY.
WHEN THERE IS MORE INFORMATION
FROM HOBOKEN, WE'LL TAKE YOU
BACK THERE LIVE.
OUR COVERAGE CONTINUES HERE.
IN A MOMENT, THE EMOTIONAL
REACTION THAT WE'RE HEARING FROM
PARENTS WHO SAY THEY HAVE NEVER
IMAGINED THE HORROR WOULD UNFOLD
THE WAY IT DID TODAY.
THAT IS STILL AHEAD AS FOX
REPORTS LIVE FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT TONIGHT.
There is no
mass-produced human.
So we created the
extraordinarily
comfortable Sleep Number
Experience.
around a bed with DualAir
Technology that allows you
to adjust to the support
your body needs - each of
your bodies.
Our sleep professionals will
help you find
your sleep number setting.
Exclusively at a Sleep
Number store.
Sleep Number.
Comfort individualized.
This holiday season, give
the gift that's magical:
the innovative AirFit
adjustable pillow at
special 30% savings.
IS EFFICIENTLY ABSORBED IN SMALL
CONTINUOUS AMOUNTS.
Citracal Slow Release
CONTINUOUSLY RELEASES CALCIUM
PLUS D
WITH EFFICIENT ABSORPTION
IN ONE DAILY DOSE.
Citracal Slow Release.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OURENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
>> THE IDENTIFICATION.
WE HAVE PRELIMINARY I.D.'S, BUT
OF TWO DO IT LEGALLY BY LAW AND
PROPERLY.
WE WOULD EXPECT THAT THE
LIEUTENANT AND I WILL BE HERE
FIRST THING IN THE MORNING
BETWEEN 7 AND 8:00  O'CLOCK AND
BY THAT TIME, WE'RE HOPING TO
HAVE POSITIVE IDENTIFICATIONS OF
ALL THE DECEASED AT THAT TIME.
WE WILL SEND YOU OUT A NEWS
RELEASE, A PRESS RELEASE, IF
YOU'RE NOT ON OUR E-MAIL LIST,
GET IT OFF THE A.P.
PRIMARILY IT WILL INCLUDE ALL
THE DETAILS WE'VE GIVEN YOU FOR
ALL THE BRIEFINGS WE'VE GIVEN
YOU DURING THIS EVENING.
I SEE NO NEED TO KEEP YOU ALL
HERE TONIGHT.
DO WHAT YOU FEEL IS CORRECT, BUT
WE WILL DO NO MORE BRIEFINGS
TONIGHT.
GOING TO AGAIN, DEFER 'TIL
PROBABLY 8:00  O'CLOCK TOMORROW
MORNING.
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE SHOOTING FOR.
COUPLE QUICK QUESTIONS AND I'LL
TRY AND ANSWER THEM IF I CAN.
>> ANYTHING ABOUT THE INJURED
VICTIM?
>> IT WAS A FEMALE EMPLOYEE OF
THE SCHOOL WHO WAS WOUNDED, WHO
WAS INJURED.
AND IS DOING WELL.
DEFINITELY, YES.
>> ARE ALL THE BODIES STILL
INSIDE THE SCHOOL?
>> I DON'T WANT TO GET INTO
DETAILS.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER HAS BEEN ON
THE SCENE WITH ALL THE PROPER
PERSONNEL AND THEY'LL DO WHAT
NEEDS TO BE DONE.
AGAIN, PRIMARILY WHAT WE'RE
LOOKING AT NOW IS THE POSITIVE
I.D. TO GIVE SOME CLOSURE TO
PEOPLE.
>> WE'RE HEARING SO MANY ROUNDS
WERE FIRED.
CAN YOU COMMENT ON THAT?
THIS IS GOING TO BE A VERY
PAIN-STAKING PROCESS.
>> I COULDN'T HAVE SAID IT
BETTER MYSELF.
THIS IS -- THE WAY WE
INVESTIGATE MAJOR CRIMES AND FOR
THOSE OF YOU THAT AREN'T HERE ON
A REGULAR BASIS, IT'S A VERY
METICULOUS PROCESS.
WE LEAVE NO STONE UNTURNED.
WE USE ALL THE RESOURCES WE HAVE
AVAILABLE TO US.
WE WILL DO THAT IN THIS CASE AND
THEN SOME.
THIS IS A CASE OF EXTREMELY
LARGE MAGNITUDE, AS YOU KNOW,
BETWEEN NEWTOWN AND STATE POLICE
AND OUR FEDERAL PARTNERS THAT WE
UTILIZED AND EVEN OUT OF STATE
PARTNERS WILL HELP US REACH OUT
OF STATE IF ANYTHING CROSSES THE
STATE BORDERS.
IT'S GOING TO TAKE A LONG TIME.
WE WILL BE PROCESSING THIS
BUILDING AND I'M JUST
SPECULATING RIGHT NOW, BUT AT
LEAST UNTIL SUNDAY.
>> HAVE THE PARENTS BEEN GIVEN
ACCESS TO THE BODIES OF THE
CHILDREN?
>> NO.
>> HOW ARE YOU MANAGING THE
IDENTIFICATION.
>> WE'VE PROCESS IN PLACE AND
WE'RE GOING TO ESTABLISH.
WE HAVE A PROCESS ESTABLISHED, I
SHOULD SAY, IN PLACE THAT WE'RE
GOING TO UTILIZE TO IDENTIFY
EACH INDIVIDUAL.
>> THE IDENTIFICATION TOMORROW
(INAUDIBLE).
>> CAUTIOUSLY OPTIMISTIC WE CAN
HAVE POSITIVE I.D. TOMORROW.
THAT'S THE PROFESSIONALS TELLING
US THAT, SPECIFICALLY THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER AND HIS TEAM.
OUR INVESTIGATORS AND WORKING
TOGETHER, WE'RE HOPING TO
ACCOMPLISH THAT.
THE FAMILIES HAVE BEEN NOTIFIED.
THE PRELIMINARY IDENTIFICATION
HAS BEEN MADE AND THROUGH
PROCESS OF ELIMINATION, THE
FAMILIES HAVE BEEN TOLD.
WE WANT TO BE ABSOLUTELY,
POSITIVELY SURE.
>> YOU STILL HAD YOUR EYE ON THE
SCENE EARLIER WHEN IT WAS CRAZY.
WHAT WAS THEIR ROLE?
IS THERE STILL A ROLE FOR THEM?
>> CERTAINLY, THEY'RE WITH US
WORKING WITH US.
THERE WERE FEDERAL PARTNERS FROM
THE F.B.I., ATF, ALL OFFERING A
SERVICES AND ANY SPECIALIZATION
THEY HAVE, OFFERING A ABILITY IN
CASE SOMETHING CROSSES STATE
LINES.
SIMPLY STATED, EVERYONE HAS COME
TOGETHER IN THE LAW ENFORCEMENT
COMMUNITY.
THIS IS A MASSIVE INVESTIGATION.
MANY LAW ENFORCEMENT AGENCIES
NEVER HAVE TO UNDERTAKE.
WE'RE CERTAINLY NEWTOWN, STATE
POLICE WORK SIDE BY SIDE AND
UTILIZING ANY RESOURCE THAT WE
MAY NEED AND WE'RE VERY
APPRECIATIVE OF ALL THE HELP
WE'RE GETTING.
>> YOU SAID THIS MORNING IS
THERE ANYONE BUT THE PERPETRATOR
INSIDE YET INVOLVED?
ANY ACCOMPLICE?
>> NO, AT THIS POINT IN TIME,
WE'RE CONFIDENT THAT WE HAVE THE
SHOOTER IN THIS INCIDENT.
>> IN THE CLASSROOM, EVERY CHILD
(INAUDIBLE)?
>> I'D RATHER NOT DO THAT, QUITE
FRANKLY.
I'VE BEEN A TROOPER A LONG TIME.
MY LIEUTENANT HAS BEEN IN LAW
ENFORCEMENT A LONG TIME.
IT'S JUST SOMETHING THAT SERVES
NO USEFUL PURPOSE.
IT'S HORRIFIC SCENE BETWEEN OUR
MUTUAL EXPERIENCE AND WE'VE
NEVER SEEN ANYTHING LIKE THIS.
IT'S HARD WRENCHING FOR US AS IT
IS FOR THE FAMILIES.
I JUST WOULD LIKE TO LEAVE THAT.
>> IS THERE AN ISSUE WITH THE
SCHOOL?
DID HE ATTEND THE SCHOOL?
>> WHAT WE'VE GOT TO DO, WE'RE
LOOKING AT THAT.
WE'RE LOOKING AT ALL THE
HISTORY.
WE'LL GO BACKWARDS AS FAR AS WE
HAVE TO GO IN THIS INVESTIGATION
AND HOPEFULLY WE'LL STUMBLE ON
ANSWERS AND WE'LL HOPEFULLY
NOT -- BUT WE WANT TO BE ABLE TO
BUILD A PROCESS AND BUILD A
STORY AND AN INVESTIGATION LIKE
THIS IS LIKE A PUZZLE.
WE WANT TO PUT THIS PUZZLE
TOGETHER AND FORM A COMPLETE
PICTURE SO THAT EVERYONE WITHOUT
ANY DOUBT WHATSOEVER CAN
UNDERSTAND WHAT OCCURRED.
SO WHAT I'D LIKE TO SAY IS THAT
WE'LL COME BACK TOMORROW IN THE
MORNING, LET'S SAY 8:00  O'CLOCK
IN THE MORNING, TO LET YOU KNOW
HOW WE PROGRESSED OVERNIGHT.
AS WE PREPARE THE LIST OF
POSITIVE IDENTIFICATION, I WANT
TO DO ONE LIST.
I DON'T WANT TO DO IT[-WL8LqúL
OR A COUPLE HERE OR THERE.
I WANT TO DO ONE FINAL LIST.
THE MINUTE THAT'S DONE, WE'LL BE
HERE WITH IT AND WE'LL ALSO POST
IT ON OUR WEB SITE SO THAT IT'S
AVAILABLE TO EVERYBODY.
>> HOW PROUD ARE YOU AND THE
LIEUTENANT OF YOUR OFFICERS WITH
THIS SITUATION, THE WAY THEY
WERE ABLE TO GET THOSE KIDS OUT
OF THERE AND GET AS MANY OUT AS
QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE?
>> THESE GUYS, WHEN THEY GOT TO
THE DOOR, WERE FIRST IN THE
DOOR, AND THE SURROUNDING PD'S
AND THE TROOPERS, THEIR TRAINING
KICKED IN.
THIS IS SOMETHING YOU TRAIN FOR.
YOU PLAN FOR, YOU WORK TOWARDS.
YOU HOPE YOU NEVER HAVE TO USE.
AND THEIR TRAINING KICKED IN.
THEY SAVED A LOT OF LIVES.
THEY DID A GREAT JOB.
VERY PROUD OF THEM.
>> TELL US ABOUT THE SHOOTER.
>> I'M SORRY?
>> WHAT CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT
THE SHOOTER?
>> I'D RATHER DO THAT IN THE
MORNING.
ONCE WE HAVE POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATION OF THE SHOOTER,
WE WANT TO HAVE ALL THAT
INFORMATION AND HOPEFULLY WE CAN
TIE UP SOME LOOSE ENDS FIRST
THING IN THE MORNING.
I'D LIKE TO LEAVE IT WHERE WE
ARE RIGHT NOW AND WE'LL FILL IN
THE VOIDS TOMORROW AS MUCH AS WE
POSSIBLY CAN.
I'M SORRY?
>> (INAUDIBLE).
>> MEDICAL EXAMINER IS MANAGING
THE CASES.
HE REQUESTS SOME EQUIPMENT
THAT'S BEEN BROUGHT IN FOR HIM.
THEY'RE THERE WORKING NOW.
>> HOW DID YOU FIRST HEAR ABOUT
THIS SHOOTING?
DID YOU HEAR -- WHAT WERE THE
FIRST WORDS?
>> IN A NUTSHELL, IT WAS A 911
CALL THAT CAME IN TO NEWTOWN
POLICE AND THE RESPONSE WAS
INSTANT.
>> FROM WITHIN THE SCHOOL?
>> YEAH.
>> ONE OR MULTIPLE CALLS?
>> I'M NOT SURE.
YES, I BELIEVE SO.
BUT I DON'T KNOW HOW MANY
OCCURRED.
>> (INAUDIBLE) WHAT ARE THEY
SAYING ABOUT THE FATHER AND SON?
>> WE'VE BEEN IN CONTACT WITH
ANY AUTHORITIES, OUR
INVESTIGATORS WITH ANY
AUTHORITIES THAT CAN ASSIST THEM
IN FURTHERING THEIR PORTION OF
THE INVESTIGATION.
DIE KNOW THAT NEW JERSEY HAS
BEEN MENTIONED.
THERE HAS BEEN TWO OR THREE
DIFFERENT LOCATIONS HAVE BEEN
MENTIONED, BUT NOT TO READ
ANYTHING INTO THAT.
IS IF THERE IS SOMETHING
SIGNIFICANT ABOUT REACHING OVER
A STATE LINE OR DOING SOMETHING
THAT MAY BE RELATED TO THIS
CASE, WE'RE NOT GOING TO HIDE IT
FROM THEM.
WE'LL MAKE IT AVAILABLE TO YOU
AND CERTAINLY PROVIDE WITH YOU
THAT INFORMATION.
BUT DON'T READ SOMETHING INTO IT
JUST BECAUSE YOU HEAR WE'VE GONE
TO AUTHORITIES IN ANOTHER STATE.
THAT DOESN'T MEAN ANYTHING
REALLY.
>> A NUMBER OF RESOURCES YOU
HAVE HERE FOR THIS, HOW ARE YOU
DELEGATING IN REGARD TO THE REST
OF THE STATE?
>> IT'S WORKING FINE.
WE'VE GOT PEOPLE ON EXTENDED
SHIFTS.
SOME PEOPLE WILL WORK EXTRA
HOURS AND SUFFICE IT TO SAY,
EVERYBODY IS ALL HANDS ON DECK.
WE'LL GET THIS DONE AND DO
WHATEVER IT TAKES TO ACCOMPLISH
THIS IN A TIMELY FASHION.
I'M GOING TO END IT BECAUSE WHAT
I'D LIKE TO DO IS GIVE YOU A
BRECK AND GIVE US A BREAK AND
WE'LL BE BACK AT 8:00  O'CLOCK
TOMORROW MORNING HERE.
OKAY?
THANK YOU.
>> Bill: THAT IS LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE, CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE.
FRANKLY, HE HAS BEEN A STANDUP
GENTLEMAN THROUGHOUT THE ENTIRE
DAY TODAY.
YOU JUST IMAGINE WHAT THAT MAN
HAS SEEN INSIDE THAT SCHOOL
BUILDING.
REALLY RIPS YOUR HEART OUT.
HE SAID IT HIMSELF, HE HAS NEVER
SEEN ANYTHING LIKE THIS IN HIS
LIFE.
IT DEFIES THE IMAGINATION TO SEE
WHAT HE HAS GONE THROUGH SO FAR
TODAY.
NO MORE BRIEFINGS TONIGHT.
THE INFORMATION IS FRANKLY IT'S
BEEN PRECIOUS AND FEW FOR
SEVERAL HOURS AND THERE IS A
REASON FOR THAT. THE POLICE HERE
WANT TO BE CAREFUL THAT THEY'RE
DOING EXACTLY THE RIGHT THING AT
THE RIGHT TIME WITH THE RIGHT
FACTS.
NEXT BRIEFING, HE SAID,
8:00 A.M. TOMORROW MORNING WHEN
HE BELIEVES THERE WILL BE
POSITIVE IDENTIFICATION GIVEN
NOT JUST ON THE VICTIMS, BUT
ALSO ON THE SHOOTER, THE GUNMAN
INSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
MY COLLEAGUE, JONATHAN HUNT,
BACK WITH ME THIS EVENING.
THIS IS GOING TO BE A PAINFUL
PROCESS AND IT JUST STARTS NOW.
>> IT WILL BE A REALLY PAINFUL
PROCESS.
YOU COULD HEAR THE EMOTION
THERE, BILL, IN LIEUTENANT
VANCE'S VOICE WHEN HE TALKED
ABOUT WHAT HE'S SEEN.
HE TALKED ABOUT THE TRAINING
THAT THE TEACHERS HAVE GONE
THROUGH, THE TRAINING THAT THE
FIRST RESPONDERS HAVE GONE
THROUGH.
AND HOW THAT KICKS IN.
BUT AT THE SAME TIME, HE HAD TO
ADMIT THIS THAT THERE IS NO WAY
YOU CAN TRAIN FULLY FOR
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
THAT'S WHY WE HEARD AND WE WERE
TALKING ABOUT IT EARLIER, THE
REPORTS THAT MANY OF THESE FIRST
RESPONDERS WERE LEAVING THAT
SCHOOL IN TEARS.
JUST IMAGINE WITNESSING THAT
SLAUGHTER, THE BODIES OF THOSE
TINY CHILDREN ON THE GROUND.
>> Bill: YEAH.
THE SCHOOL ITSELF IS A COUPLE
HUNDRED YARDS FROM OUR LOCATION
HERE.
WE'RE AT A LOCAL PARK CALLED
TREADWELL PARK.
YOU KNOW THAT THOSE KIDS PLAYED
HERE AFTER SCHOOL AND THEY
PROBABLY SPENT THE WEEKENDS HERE
WITH THEIR FAMILY, SOCCER
FIELDS, FOOTBALL FIELDS.
YOU GO THROUGH THE FOREST HERE,
DOWN A HILL BEFORE YOU COME UPON
THE SCHOOL.
INSIDE THAT SCHOOL IS THE CRIME
SCENE THAT THEY'RE TRYING TO
PIECE TOGETHER SO THAT WE HAVE A
BETTER IDEA WHAT IN THE WORLD
WAS GOING ON INSIDE THIS YOUNG
MAN'S MIND.
>> AND YOU THINK ABOUT WHAT THE
COMMUNITY IS GOING THROUGH, JUST
TO GET BACK TO YOUR POINT ABOUT
THE KIDS PLAYING HERE.
THIS IS A COMMUNITY.
>> SANDY HOOK ITSELF, ABOUT
10,000.
SO EVERYBODY IS GOING TO KNOW
SOMEBODY AFFECTED BY THIS AND
THEN ALL THE QUESTIONS ARE GOING
TO BE ASKED WHAT, ON EARTH WAS
GOING THROUGH THE MIND OF ADAM
LANZA, WHO HAS BEEN IDENTIFIED
AS THE SHOOTER BY FEDERAL
OFFICIALS TALKING TO OUR OWN
RICK LEVENTHAL.
HE APPARENTLY WOKE THUMB
MORNING, SHOT HIS MOTHER IN THE
FACE, WENT TO HER SCHOOL, WENT
INTO THAT SCHOOL AND THEN FOR
REASONS WE CAN NOT FATHOM,
MURDER SOD MANY CHILDREN.
>> Bill: JONATHAN, WE'LL SPEAK
AGAIN HAD A LITTLE BIT.
CHRISTMAS IS 11 DAYS AWAY.
SUPPOSED TO BE LIKE
THIS.
BACK LIVE IN NEWTOWN AS OUR
COVERAGE CONTINUES.
>> Bill: ANOTHER LIVE LOOK