I'M JUST ASKING THE PRESIDENT TO
GET INVOLVED AT THIS POINT.
>> Sean: I PUT A PETITION ON
MY
WEBSITE, HANNITY.COM, AND PEOPLE
CAN HELP AND YOU GUYS ARE GOING
TO BE IN OUR THOUGHTS AND
PRAYERS AND OUR HOPE IS THAT JON
GETS HOME BEFORE CHRISTMAS AND
SOMEBODY AT THE STATE
DEPARTMENT D, SOMEBODY AT THE
WHITE HOUSE STEPS UP AND HANDLES
THIS.
THANK YOU BOTH FOR BEING WITH
US.
>> THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU FOR HAVING US.
WAY, GRETA ISE
GOING TO HAVE THE LAWYERS FOR
JON COMING UP AS SHE GOES ON THE
A FEW SECONDS
HERE.
THAT'S ALL THE TIME WE HAVE
LEFT.
AS W ALWAYS, THANKS FOR BEING WH
US.
GRETA WILL HAVE THAT, THE HOT
DOG GUY, AND MORE AS SHE GOES ON
THE RECORD.
THANKS FOR BEING WITH US, AND
HOPE YOU HAVE A GREAT NIGHT.
IT'S OFFICIAL.
UN AMBASSADOR WILL NOT REPLACE
HILLARY CLINTON AS SECRETARY OF
STATE.
THE EMBATTLED AMBASSADOR
WITHDRAWING HER NAME FROM
CONSIDERATION.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT THAT IN
MINUTES.
FIRST, MICHIGAN POLICE ON THE
HUNT FOR THE VIOLENT MASKED
PROTESTERS WANTED FOR RIPPING
DOWN A TENT NEAR THE STATE
CAPITOL AND TERRORIZING THOSE
INSIDE THE TENT.
THAT VIOLENCE WAS SPARKED BY THE
PASSAGE OF THE RIGHT-TO-WORK
LAW.
THE UNION SUPPORTERS, TEARING
DOWN THE TENT WITH
UNION SUPPORTERS TORE DOWN THE
TENT WITH PEOPLE INSIDE IT.
TENT BELONGED TO THE
CONSERVATIVE GROUP AMERICANS FOR
PROSPERITY.
TODAY THE FILING OF A POLICE
COMPLAINT.
YOU'LL HEAR THE LATEST FROM
POLICE IN JUST ONE MINUTE, BUT
FIRST, ALSO CAUGHT UNDER THAT
TENT AS IT WAS COMING DOWN,
VENDOR CLINT TARVER KNOWN AS THE
HOT DOG GUY.
HE WAS JUST SELLING HOT DOGS
WHEN HE GOT THE SCARE OF HIS
LIFE.
GOT THE CARE OF HIS
SO OTHER TELL ME WHAT HAPPENED?
YOU GOT HIRED TO SELL HOTDOGS,
YOU GOT THERE AT 10:00 IN THE
MORNING.
TAKE IT FROM THERE.
>> AT 10:00 IN THE MORNING, I
SET UP TO SELL HOTDOGS.
AT 10:30, I WAS READY TO SELL
HOTDOGS.
EVERYONE HAD TO HAVE A TICKET TO
RECEIVE A HOTDOG.
SO -- I GUESS ABOUT 11:30, MAYBE
A QUARTER TO 12, TWO GUYS CAME
INTO THE TENT.
AND ONE WAS WEARING THE MASK
LOOKS LIKE A DEVIL'S MASK.
THE OTHER ONE WAS WEARING A SKI
PLAIVEG.
AND SO, YOU KNOW -- SKI MASK.
YOU KNOW, I THOUGHT THEY WERE
HAVING SOME FUN.
JUST FUN.
SO THE GUY TOOK THEIR MAIVES
OFF.
THEY HAD A TICKET.
I GAVE NEM A HOTDOG.
AS SOON AS THEY GOT THROUGH
EATING THE HOTDOG, 3 MINUTES
LATER, THEY STARTED TO TEAR --
TURNING OVER THE COFFEE POTS,
URNS, ABOUT FOUR OF THEM.
THE TABLE GOT TURNED OVER AND BY
THAT TIME, THEY STARTED CUTTING
THE TENT.
COMING IN AND ONE OF THE
GROUNDSKEEPERS CAME IN AND SAID,
CLINT, HAVE YOU TO GET OUT OF
HERE.
THEY ARE CUTTING THE TENT.
THE TENT IS ABOUT TO COLLAPSE.
AT THAT TIME, I WAS TRYING TO
SAVE SOME OF MY STUFF, BUT I
COULDN'T.
BY THAT TIME, IT HAD COLLAPSED
AND I HAD TO CRAWL FROM UNDER
THE TENT TO GET AWAY.
AND SO, I CLIMBED OUT AND I WAS
JUST STANDING THERE AND AS I WAS
STANDING THERE.
THEY FORMED A LINE... AND THEY
WALKED ACROSS THE TENT, STOMPING
EVERYTHING THAT WAS IN THEIR
PATH.
TURNING OVER MY TABLES.
MY CATERING EQUIPMENT.
HOTDOGS, MY CHILI, MY CHEESE, MY
SAUERKRAUT, EVERYTHING.
MY POP.
THEY THREW MY POP AROUND.
THEY HOLLERED RACIAL SLUR, THE
"N" WORD.
I WAS AN UNCLE TOM.
I HAD NO BUSINESS ON THIS SIDE.
BUT I WAS TRYING TO EXPLAIN TO
THEM THAT I AM A HOTDOG VENDOR.
I WAS HIRED BY THESE PEOPLE TO
COME IN AND SELL HOTDOGS TO
PEOPLE WHO THIS TICKS.
THAT'S WHAT I DO.
I HAVE BEEN DOING IT FOR 16
YEARS, GRETA.
THAT'S WHAT I WAS THERE FOR.
I GOT CAUGHT UP IN THAT.
>> GRETA: WERE YOU EVER ABLE TO
SEE THEIR FACES.
OR WERE THEY AT ALL TIME IT'S.
>> NO!
THEY TOOK THEIR MASKS OFF AND I
GAVE THEM A HOTDOG.
ONE WAS A RATHER THIN FELLA.
THE OTHER ONE, I CAN'T REMEMBER
HIS FACE.
I JUST THE OTHER GUY WAS A THIN
GUY.
YOUNG GUY.
>> GRETA: OTHER THAN THE VERY
OFFENSIVE RACIAL SLURS, DID THEY
SAY ANYTHING ABOUT RIGHT TO WORK
OR TO INDICATE WHAT SIDE OF THE
FIGHT THEY WERE ON, THIS BATTLE
OR WHETHER THEY WERE OUTSIDE
AGITATORS?
>> NO, THE PEOPLE WHO WERE
PROTESTING AGAINST THE
RIGHT-TO-WORK PEOPLE.
THEY WERE SO ANGRY AT THESE
PEOPLE.
AND THAT -- I GUESS THEY THOUGHT
I WAS PART OF IT AND THEY
STARTED -- CALLING ME THE "N"
WORD.
THEY EVEN SPIT ON A COUPLE OF
PEOPLE.
THEY WERE OUT OF ORDER, GRETA.
TOTALLY.
>> GRETA: DID OTHERS JOIN IN OR
DID ANY OF THE SORT OF
PROTESTERS TRY TO STOP THEM OR
DID EVERYBODY STAND BY WHILE YOU
GOT TERRORIZED AND POSSIBLY VERY
HURTED WITH THE TENT?
>> NO.
THERE WERE SOME PEOPLE THAT WAS
SAFETY.
THEY HAD SAFETY THINGS ON, SO
THEY WERE TRYING TO CALM THE
CROWD DOWN.
BUT THEY KIND OF LIKE, PUSHED
THEM ASIDE AND LIKE I WAS
TELLING MY WIFE, SHE WAS SO
UPSET.
I WAS TELLING HER THAT THESE
GUYS WAS TELLING THEM, HEY, THIS
IS NOT MARTIN LUTHER KING TIME.
YOU KNOW, WE ARE NOT GOING TO GO
FOR THIS PEACE STUFF ANYMORE.
WE WANT IT THIS WAY.
WE GOING TO "F" THIS, "F" THAT.
IT WAS JUST CRAZY IRVETION --
CRAZY.
>> GRETA: CLINT, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
SORRY HUTO GO THROUGH THAT.
>> THANK YOU.
>> GRETA: TODAY, MEMBERS OF
AMERICANS FOR PROSPERITY FILING
A POLICE COMPLAINT.
LAST NIGHT, THEY WENT RECORD
ROAR, TELLING US ABOUT THE
TERRIFYING TENT ATTACK.
>> IT WAS VERY SCARY.
TWO MEN CAME IN IN SKI MASKS.
THEY HAD BOX CUTIRS OR KNIVES.
THEY STARTED TO CUT THE CANVAS
STRAPPED THAT TETHERED THE TENT
TO THE GROUND.
THEY STARTED TO FLIP OVER THE
TABLES THAT HAD HOT COUGHO IT.
IT WAS -- COFFEE ON IT.
IT WAS SCARY AND A LOT OF PEOPLE
FELT ACHERY, THEY FELT LIKE
THEIR PERSONAL SPACE HAD BEEN
INVADED AND THEIR RIGHT TO HAVE
THEIR VOICE HEARD WAS BEING
TRAMPLED ON.
>> GRETA: FOR YOU, DAVID, WHAT
WAS IT LIKE?
>> GOOD EVENING, GRETA.
IT WAS PRETTY INTENSE -- WE HAD
TO POST PEOPLE OUT BY THE STRAPS
TO KEEP THEM FROM UNDOING THEM
TO MAKE THE TENT CAVE IN.
WHEN THE COFFEE URNS WERE THROWN
OVER AND THE TABLES, WE KNEW
THEY WERE INSIDE.
WE CAME BACK AROUND AND WENT
INTO THE TENT.
IT WAS ALMOST COLLAPSED BY THEN.
>> GRETA: WHAT ARE THE POLICE
DOING ABOUT ALL OF THIS?
MICHIGAN STATE POLICE INSPECTOR
IS HERE.
GOOD EVENING.
>> GOOD EVENING, GRETA.
>> GRETA: WERE YOU OUTSIDE ON
THE GROUNDS YESTERDAY WHEN THIS
WENT DOWN?
>> I WAS ALL OVER THE CAPITOL,
GRETA.
BUT WHEN THIS HAD
PLATOONS SURROUNDING THE
BUILDING, KEEPING TRACK OF THE
CROWD.
WE DO KNOW WHERE THE TENTS WERE.
HOWEVER, HAVING A GROUND VIEW
AND THE TENTS BEING ABOUT 40
DEEP INTO THE CROWD, WE WERE
UNABLE TO SEE WHAT WAS GOING ON.
HOWEVER, WHEN OUR HELICOPTER
REPORTED THAT IT LOOKED LIKE THE
TWO CANOPIES HAD COLLAPSED, WE
SENT TWO PLATOONS OF TROOPERS
THERE TO MAKE SURE THAT NOBODY
WAS INJURED OR TRAPPED UNDER THE
TENTS.
BY THE TIME OUR TROOPERS WORKED
THEIR WAY THROUGH THE CROWDS,
THE PEOPLE WERE OUT OF THE
TENTS.
>> GRETA: NOW, I TAKE IT NO
ARRESTS WERE MADE ON THE SCENE,
THAT YOU DIDN'T GET THE PLATOONS
OR SINGLE POLICE OFFICERS OVER
TO THE AREA TO MAKE THE ARREST
FOR THESE TWO WHO HAD STARTED
THIS DESTRUCTION?
>> NO, MA'AM.
A CROWD OF THIS SIZE, THIS SIZE
KIND OF A MOB-LIKE GROUP AT THAT
TIME, IS VERY FLUID.
WE HAD OUR HANDS FULL,
MAINTAINING THE CONTROL OF THE
CROWD.
BUT WHEN OUR TWO PLATOONS OF
TROOPERS WERE THERE, NOBODY
REPORTED ANY INJURIES NOR DID
ANYBODY REPORT ANY DAMAGE OR
WANT TO FILE A DOM PLAINT --
COMPLAINT AT THAT TIME.
>> GRETA: WHETHER OR NOT ANYONE
REPORTS DAMAGING DOESN'T MEAN
THERE HASN'T BEEN A CRIME, WHEN
SOMEBODY IS CUTTING DOWN A TENT
AND TERRORIZING AND SCARYING
PEOPLE.
YOU HAVE A CRIME.
WOULD YOU NOT AGREE?
>> YES, MA'AM.
HOWEVER THE TENTS WERE A LOW
PRIORITY AT THAT TIME THAT.
HAPPENED ON TUESDAY AND AT 2:00
TODAY, THE RIGHT TO WORK GROUP
DID FILE A COMPLAINT WITH THE
MICHIGAN STATE POLICE.
AND WE WILL INVESTIGATE THAT.
>> GRETA: DO YOU HAVE -- DID YOU
HAVE ALL THE VIDEO YOU NEED TO
PERHAPS IDENTIFY -- WE HAVE SOME
VIDEO, OBVIOUSLY, DO YOU HAVE
THE TWO WHO ORIGINALLY WENT INTO
THE TENT WITH THE MASKS.
THEY WENT THEIR MASKS OFF.
>> WE HAVE LIMITED VIDEO.
AND OUR DETECTIVES HAVE NOT HAD
A CHANCE TO CHECK THAT YET.
AGAIN, THIS REPORT CAME IN AT
2:30 AND IT WAS JUST BARELY
PROCESSED TODAY.
>> GRETA: HAVE YOU HEARD ANY
REPORT INCONSISTENT WITH WHAT
OUR GUESTS HAVE SAID FROM LAST
NIGHT AND TONIGHT, OUR LIVE
GUESTS?
>> NO, MA'AM.
YOU KNOW, THERE WAS AN ASSAULT
ON A REPORTER ALSO.
AND THAT INDIVIDUAL HAS NOT
FILED A POLICE REPORT WITH THE
STATE POLICE YET YEERGHT.
>> GRETA: YOU KNOW, YOU WATCH
THIS AND IT'S DISGUSTING.
DO YOU AGREE?
THE VIOLENCE -- I MEAN, A HOTDOG
SELLING GUY -- I MEAN, WHY DO
THAT TO HIM?
>> MR. TARVAR IS AN INSTITUTION
IN DOWNTOWN LANSING.
VIEATEN HIS HOTDOGS MANY TIMES.
YOU KNOW, OVERALL, A CROWD OF
OVER 12,000 WERE WELL BEHAVED.
UNFORTUNATELY, THERE WERE A
HANDFUL OF PEOPLE, WHETHER IT
WAS EMOTION OR WHATEVER, LET
THINGS GET OUT OF CONTROL AND
JUST GAVE THIS ENTIRE PROTEST A
BAD REPUTATION.
>> GRETA: I AM CURIOUS IF HE'S
AN INSTITUTION, WHETHER OR NOT
HE WAS TARGETED IN PARTICULAR
BECAUSE HE IS OBVIOUSLY SELLING
HOTDOGS INSIDE THE TENT OF ONE
SIDE OF THIS, IN THIS INSTANCE,
THE PEOPLE WHO ARE SUPPORTING
THE NEW LAW.
WAS HE TARGETD?
THE RACIAL SLUSHES HURLED AT
HIM?
>> GRETA:.
>> WELL, THAT'S PART OF THE
CROWD MENTALITY.
HE HAPPENED TO BE AT THE WRONG
PLACE AT THE RIGHT TIME, WITH
THE WRONG GROUP, AS FAR AS THE
OTHER PROTESTERS FELT.
>> GRETA: ONE THING IS CERTAIN,
THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO KNOW WHO
DID THIS TO THIS MAN AND THE
OTHER PEOPLE, CUTTING DOWN THE
TENT.
LUCKY THAT PEOPLE WEREN'T
MOTHERED, I SUPPOSE.
BY THE TENT.
IF PEOPLE HAVE THE DISEENS TOW
COME FORWARD AND GIVE YOU SOME
TIPS.
I HOPE YOU GET THEM.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
>> I HOPE IF PEOPLE DO HAVE
INFORMATION, THEY DO PRESENT IT
TO THE MICHIGAN STATE POLICE.
>> GRETA: THANK YOU, SIR.
>> YES, MA'AM.
>> GRETA: U.N. AMBASSADOR AND
HER ABRUPT WITHDRAWAL FROM THE
RAWNING FOR THE SECRETARY OF
STATE.
>> THE SECOND BIG STORY, SUSAN
RICE.
JUST IN THE LAST COUPLE OF HOUR,
CALL THEEING THE PRESIDENT,
SAYING SHE IS PULLING HER NAME
OUT OF CONSIDERATION FOR
SECRETARY OF STATE, ALL BECAUSE
OF THAT CONTROVERSY OVER
BENGHAZI, HER REACTION TO THE
TERROR ATTACK, WHETHER OR NOT
SHE MISLED THE PUBLIC.
>> BEST ASSESSMENT WE HAVE TODAY
IS THAT IN FACT, THIS WAS NOT A
PRE-PLANNED, PREMADE TITTED --
PREMEDITATED ATTACK.
>> I AM MORE TROUBLED TODAY,
KNOWING, HAVING MET WITH THE
ACTING DIRECTOR OF THE CIA AND
AMBASSADOR RICE.
>> IT WAS A PONTANEOUS REACTION
TO WHAT HAD JUST TRANSPIRED IN
CAIRO, AS A CONSEQUENCE OF THE
VIDEO.
>> THE OBSESSIVE FOCUS ON
AMBASSADOR RICE'S APPEARANCE ON
A SERIES OF SUNDAY SHOWS IS
MISPLACED AND MISGUIDED.
>> WHY DID THE ADMINISTRATION
PULT HER OUT THERE AS THE
SPOKESPERSON?
>> IF SENATOR McCAIN AND
SENATOR GRAHAM AND OTHERS WANT
TO GO AFTER SOMEBODY, THEY
SHOULD GO AFTER ME.
>> SUSAN RICE SHOULD HAVE KNOWN
BETTER.
IF SHE DIDN'T KNOW BETTER, SHE'S
NOT QUALIFIED.
>> BUT FOR THEM TO GO AFTER THE
U.N. AMBASSADOR, WHO HAD NOTHING
TO DO WITH BENGHAZI AND WAS
SIMPLY MAKING A PRESENTATION,
BASED ON INTELLIGENCE THAT SHE
HAD RECEIVED THAT BEMIMPED HER
REPUTATION IS OUTRAGEOUS.
>> I AM MORE DISTURBED NOW THAN
I WAS BEFORE THAT THE 16th
OF SEPTEMBER EXPLANATION ABOUT
HOW FOUR AMERICANS DIED IN
BENGHAZI, LIBYA, BY AMBASSADOR
RICE, I THINK DOES NOT DO
JUSTICE TO THE REALITY AT THE
TIME.
AND IN MINDSIGHT CLEARLY WAS
COMPLETELY WRONG.
>> GRETA: IN A LETTER TO
PRESIDENT OBAMA, A SHORT TIME
AGO, AMBASSADOR RICE, WRITING IN
PART...
SHE CONTINUES AND SAYS...
SENATOR LINDSAY GRAHAM JOINS US.
>> GOOD EVENING.
>> GRETA: YOUR RESPONSE TO THE
LETTER THAT THE AMBASSADOR SENT
TO THE PRESIDENT, THREE OR FOUR
PARAGRAPH, ACCUSING THOSE WHO
CRITICIZE HER OF POLITICIZING IT
AND CAUSING AN IRRESPONSIBLE
DISAKZ DISTRACTION.
ARE YOU POLITICIZING IT?
ARE YOU CAUSING AN IRRESPONSIBLE
DISTRACTION?
>> I THINK THE PROBLEM HERE IS
THAT SHE WENT ON NATIONAL
TELEVISION, FIVE DAYS AFTER THE
ATTACK THAT KILLED FOUR
AMERICANS AND TOLD A STORY THAT
IS NOT BASED ON ANY REALITY THAT
I HAVE SEEN.
SHE TOLD A POLITICAL STORY THREE
WEEKS BEFORE THE ELECTION.
THEY SANITIZED THE INTELLIGENCE.
SHE SAYS THE CONSULATE WAS
STRONG, SUBSTANTIALLY AND
SIGNIFICANTLY DEFENDED.
NOTHING COULD BE FURTHER FROM
THE TRUTH.
SHE INDICATED THAT AL QAEDA WAS
DECIMATED, TRYING TO CONTINUE
THE NARRATIVE THAT THE PRESIDENT
HAD BEEN TALKING ABOUT SINCE THE
DEATH OF BIN LADEN, I COLD HER
ACCOUNTABLE AND -- I HOLD HER
ACCOUNTABLE AND RESPONSIBLE FOR
MISLEADING THE AMERICAN PEOPLE.
I THINK SHE WAS CHOSE TONE
TELL -- FOR A REASON.
IF HE DIDN'T KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT
BENGHAZI, AS THE PRESIDENT
INDICATED, WHY DID THEY PICK
HER?
I THOUGHT SHE WAS THE MOST
POLITICALLY COMPLIANT PERSON
THEY COULD FIND.
AND THE STORY SHE TOLD DOESN'T
WITHSTAND SCRUTINY.
>> GRETA: DO YOU FACTOR INTO THE
EQUATION -- I CONFESS THAT I
DO -- SHE WENT ON FIVE SHOWS AND
IT TOOK 73 DAYS BEFORE SHE SAID
ANYTHING DIFFERENT AND THAT WAS
TO U.S. SENATORS BEHIND CLOSED
DOORS, BUT IT TOOK 73 DAYS
FORLER TO SPEAK OUT, NOT EVEN
PUBLICLY, BUT BEHIND CLOSED
DOORS.
>> I I DON'T THINK SHE WOULD
HAVE EVER SAID SHE WAS WRONG.
THIS IS NOT ABOUT SUSAN RICE.
THE PRESIDENT SAID, IF YOU HAVE
A PROBLEM WITH BENGHAZI -- I
DO -- IT IS NOT PICKING ON THE
PRESIDENT.
IT IS TRYING TO EXPOSE A
NATIONAL SECURITY FAILURE, A
DEBACLE.
I HOLD THE PRESIDENT ACCOUNTABLE
MORE THAN ANYTHINGCH -- MORE
THAN ANYONE ELSE.
IT SHOULD HAVE BEEN CLOSED OR
REINFORCED BEFORE THE ATTACK ON
9/11.
THERE IS NOTHING TO DO TO HELP
THE PEOPLE.
WHERE WAS HE AS COMMANDENER
CHIEF.
HAVE YOU TWO MOVIES BEING MADE
IN THE RAID ON BIN LADEN.
YOU DON'T KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT
WHAT THE PRESIDENT DID IN THE
SEVEN HOURS OF THE ATTACK.
AND AFTERWARD, THE PRESIDENT
TRIED TO BLAME THIS ON A VIDEO
AND A MOB AND A DEMONSTRATION
THAT NEVER EXISTED.
BUT SUSAN RICE, IN MY OPINION,
MISLED THE PUBLIC.
THERE ARE OTHER PROBLEMS WITH
HER TIME AND POLITICS AND
NATIONAL FOREIGN AFFAIRS ARENA.
HER PROBLEMS WERE DEEPER THAN ME
AND DEEPER THAN BENGHAZI.
BUT WE WON'T LET THIS GO.
HOW COULD FOR SEVEN HOURS,
NOBODY COME TO THE AID OF THE
PEOPLE DURING THE ATTACK?
WHY DID WE LEAVE THE CONSULATE
OPEN?
WHERE WAS THE PRESIDENT WHEN THE
BRITISH DECIDED TO CLOSE THEIR
CONSULATE IN JUNE AND
AFTERWARDS, HOW DID THE
INTELLIGENCE GET SO SCREWED UP?
WE ARE GOING TO KEEP PRESSING
THIS SO WE CAN LEARN FROM IT AND
NOT HAVE IT HAPPEN AGAIN.
>> GRETA: THANK YOU, SIR.
>> THANK YOU.
>> GRETA: FORMER U.N. AMBASSADOR
JOHN BOLTON IS HERE.
>> GLAD TO BE HERE.
>> GRETA: YOU HEARD ME SAY TO
THE SENATOR NHER LETTER TO THE
PRESIDENT, SHE HAS AN OP-ED
PIECE IN THE WASHINGTON POST,
POLITICIZING, IRRESPONSIBLE
DISTRACTION, CRITICS OF HER AND
IN THE WASHINGTON POST ARTICLE,
SHE REFERS TO THE DEBATE ABOUT
HER AS BEING A POLITICAL
FOOTBALL.
HOW DO WE KNOW IF SHE IS RIGHT
OR WHETHER OR NOT THERE IS A
FAIR SCRUTINY OF A GOVERNMENT
EMPLOYEE.
>> I THINK IT'S ALWAYS FAIR
SCRUTINY.
EVERYTHING YOU SAY IN PUBLIC
WHEN YOU ARE A SENIOR GOVERNMENT
OFFICIAL IS OPEN TO QUESTION.
AND IN FACT HERE, THE
ADMINISTRATION TRIED TO HAVE IT
BOTH WAYS.
THEY TRIED TO GET THEIR STORY
LINE OUT THAT THE KILLINGS IN
BENGHAZI WERE CAUSED BY THE
MUHAMMAD VIDEO.
WHEN THE DATA SHOWED THAT THAT
WAS FANTASY, THEY TRIED TO
STONEWALL PAST THE ELECTION TO
STONEWALL PAST THE POSSIBLE
NOMINATION OF SECRETARY OF STATE
AND IT HAS FALLEN APART.
SUSAN RICE MAY BE AN UNFORTUNATE
VICTIM.
BUT THIS IS ALL DUE TO THE
PRESIDENT'S OWN STRATEGY.
>> GRETA: YOU KNOW, SHE IS
WITHDRAWING HER NAME FROM
CONSIDERATION.
SHE WAS NEVER NOMINATED.
I DON'T KNOW IF THE PRESIDENT
SAID HE INTENDED TO NOMINATE
HER.
THIS IS LIKE EYE COULD SUBMIT A
LETTER WITHDRAWING MY NAME FROM
CONSIDERATION.
>> SURE, I COULD SIT AT HOME BY
THE PHONE AND WAIT FOR HIS CALL
TO TO NOMINATE ME.
>> GRETA: WHY DID SHE SEND THAT
LETTER AND MAKE IT PUBLIC AND
WHY TONIGHT?
>> I THINK THEY HAD COME TO A
POLITICAL CONCLUSION THAT IT WAS
TOO COST THREE GO FORWARD AND
SHE WANTED TO GET HER TWO CENTS
WORTH IN ON THAT.
I WOULD BE SURPRISED NOW IF
AFTER A FEW INTERVIEWS ON
FRIENDLY TELEVISION NETWORKS
TONIGHT, THERE IS MUCH MORE
DISCUSSION ABOUT.
IT I THINK THE ADMINISTRATION
WANTS TO GET THIS OFF THE RADAR
SCREEN.
SO I AM ENCOURAGED THAT SENATOR
GRAHAM AND I AM SURE OTHERS IN
CONGRESS, ARE NOT GOING TO LET
IT GO.
NOW THAT SUSAN RICE IS OUT OF
THE PICTURE, I THINK THIS OPENS
THE WAY, BEGINNING NEXT WEEK
WITH HILLARY CLINTON'S TESTIMONY
IN CONGRESS, AS TO WHAT ACTUALLY
HAPPENED.
>> GRETA: IT'S INTERESTING IN
HER LETTER TO THE PRESIDENT, SHE
STALKS ABOUT WHAT SHE SAYS ARE
THE SUCCESSES THAT SHE IS PART
OF WITH THE ADMINISTRATION AND
ONE OF THEM IS INCREASING THE
INTERNATIONAL PRESSURE ON IRAN
AND NORTH KOREA WITH THE
TOUGHEST SANCTIONS EVER.
THAT DID HAPPEN, BUT WE HAVEN'T
GOTTEN ANYWHERE.
THEY ARE MOVING FORWARD WITH THE
NUCLEAR WEAPONS PROGRAM.
NORTH KOREA INTEREST A MISSILE
LAUNCH.
>> THE SANCTIONS FROM THE PAST
FOUR YEARS ARE MARGINAL,
COMPARED TO THE SANCTIONS
IMPOSED BEFORE, YET IRAN IS EVER
CLOSER TO NUCLEAR WEAPONS, NORTH
KOREA LAUNCHED A SATELLITE INTO
-- BIT.
THE WORLD IS MORE DANGEROUS, NOT
BECAUSE OF SUSAN RICE, BUT
BECAUSE OF BARACK OBAMA.
>> GRETA: I AM HIGHLY CRITICAL
THAT SHE ROLLED OUT FOR 73 DAYS
AND DIDN'T CORRECT IT AND SHOULD
HAVE.
I DON'T THINK WE SHOULD HAVE HAD
THAT MYSTERY LINGERING.
PEOPLE I TALKED TO SAY SHE HAS
BEEN VERY HELPFUL IN THE SOUTH
SUDAN AND SAVING LIVES THERE IN
A VERY TERRIBLE SITUATION.
I WILL GIVE HER CREDIT FOR THAT.
>> OKAY.
>> GRETA: THANK YOU, SIR.
>> THANK YOU.
>> GRETA: STRAIGHT AHEAD, HOW DO
WE LET THIS HAPPEN?
A U.S. MARINE CHAINED UP IN A
DANGEROUS MEXICAN PRISON.
THE PARENTS GETTING HORRIFYING
CALLS ABOUT SENDING MOAN TOW
SAVE HIS LIFE.
THAT DISTURBING STORY IS NEXT.
AND CONGRESSMAN JASON CHAFITS
ACCUSING THE STATE DEPARTMENT OF
HIDING BENGHAZI SURVIVORS.
HE IS HERE.
AND CAUGHT ON CAMERA, IF YOU
THINK OUR CONGRESS FIGHTS, TAKE
A LOOK AT THIS.
WHAT LED TO THE GOVERNMENT
BRAWL?
WHERE IN THE WORLD IS THIS?
YOU WILL SEE A LOT MORE, COMING
UP
From the best
players in history
to the number 1 club
in the world.
The potential of
Manchester United unlocked.
NYSE Euronext.
Unlocking the world's potential.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with uimited
talk and text.
by HTC for $49.99.
IT'S PART OF WHAT YOU
SLOVE ABOUT HER.ESSING.
BUT YOUR ERECTILE DYSFUNCTION -
YOU KNOW, THAT COULD BE
A QUESTION OF BLOOD FLOW.
CIALIS TADALAFIL
FOR DAILY USE
HELPS YOU BE READY
ANYTIME THE
MOMENT'S RIGHT.
YOU CAN BE MORE CONFIDENT
IN YOUR ABILITY TO BE READY.
AND THE SAME CIALIS IS THE ONLY
DAILY ED TABLET APPROVED
TO TREAT ED AND
SYMPTOMS OF BPH,
LIKE NEEDING TO GO
FREQUENTLY OR URGENTLY.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT ALL
YOUR MEDICAL CONDITIONS
AND MEDICATIONS,
AND ASK IF YOUR HEART IS HEALTHY
ENOUGH FOR SEXUAL ACTIVITY.
DO NOT TAKE CIALIS IF YOU TAKE
NITRATES FOR CHEST PAIN,
AS THIS MAY CAUSE AN UNSAFE
DROP IN BLOOD PRESSURE.
DO NOT DRINK ALCOHOL
IN EXCESS WITH CIALIS.
SIDE EFFECTS MAY INCLUDE
HEADACHE, UPSET STOMACH,
DELAYED BACKACHE OR MUSCLE ACHE.
TO AVOID LONG-TERM INJURY,
SEEK IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
FOR AN ERECTION LASTING
MOREHAN FOUR HOURS.
IF YOU HAVE ANY SUDDEN DECREASE
OR LOSS IN HEARING OR VISION,
OR IF YOU HAVE ANY ALLERGIC
REACTIONS SUCH AS RASH,
HIVES, SWELLING OF THE LIPS,
TONGUE OR THROAT,
OR DIFFICULTY BREATHING
OR SWALLOWING,
STOP TAKING CIALIS AND GET
MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY.
ASK YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT CIALIS
FOR DAILY USE
AND A 30-TABLET FREE TRIAL.
>> GRETA: HE SURVIVES IRAQ AND
AFGHANISTAN, BUT A U.S. MARINE
IS FIGHT EGG VERY DANGEROUS
BATTLE IN MEXICO, FIGHTING TO
STAY ALIVE.
HE IS IN A VICIOUS MEXICAN
PRISON AND WORSE, HE IS UNDER
CONSTANT THREATS FROM VIOLENT
DRUG CARTELS.
HE WAS ARRESTED, PASSING THROUGH
A MEXICAN BORDER CITY ON THE WAY
TO COSTA RICA.
HE WAS ARRESTED FOR CARRYING HIS
GRANDFATHER'S ANTIQUE SHOTGUN.
ON THE U.S. SIDE OF THE BORDER,
AN AGENT TOLD HIM THE GUN WAS
LEGAL, AS LONG AS HE DECLARED IT
TO MEXICAN AUTHORITIES.
SO THAT'S WHAT HE DID AND THAT'S
WHAT GOT HIM ARRESTED.
THE PARENTS ARE BEGGING THE
OBAMA ADMINISTRATION TO HELP
SAVE HIS SON'S LIFE.
WE HAVE THE ATTORNEY FOR HAMAR
HERE.
>> GOOD TO BE WITH YOU.
>> GRETA: NICE TO HAVE YOU HERE.
WHY CAN'TY GET HIM OUT OF JAIL?
WHAT'S WRONG?
>> OKAY.
RIGHT NOW, THERE IS A FLIEL
MEXICO, TRIALS START AT CERTAIN
POINTS AND THERE IS DIFFERENT
HEARINGS, LIKE IN THE UNITED
STATES OF AMERICA.
AND WE ARE READY TO GO WITH OUR
EXPERTS AND ALSO WE HAVE MOTIONS
AND WE HAVE TWO INJUNCTIONS FOR
EXCLUSION OF EVIDENCE FOR
VIOLATION OF HIS CONSTITUTIONAL
RIGHTS.
>> GRETA: WHEN IS THIS TRIAL
DATE?
>> THE TRIAL DATE'S BEEN ON.
THE NEXT HEARING'S SET FOR
JANUARY 17.
THAT DATE, GRETA, WAS MOVED,
CONTINUED, FROM OCTOBER 30 OR
THEREABOUTS.
THE HEARINGS WERE SET FOR
NOVEMBER 13 AND 23 AND THEY WERE
CONTINUED BECAUSE THE MEXICANOMO
ANOTHER PLACE.
AND WE HAVE TO BRING HIM IN, THE
JUDGE WANTED TO CROSS-EXAMINE
AND WE SAID, OF COURSE.
I SAID YES.
SO HE WILL HAVE TO BE BRAWLT
BROUGHT IN FOR
CROSS-EXAMINATION.
>> GRETA: ALL RIGHT.
WHERE IS OUR STATE DEPARTMENT ON
THIS?
AND WHY CAN'T WE GET THE MEXICAN
GOVERNMENT TO HELP?
WHAT IS WRONG WITH A BOND TO GET
HIM OUT?
I SUNDAY UNDERSTAND THE PRISON
IS FILLED WITH A CARTEL, WHY YOU
GET HIM OUT ON BOND?
>> OKAY.
THERE ARE THREE ANSWERS THAT
NEED TO BE SAID.
FIRST OF ALL, ON BOND.
THIS PARTICULAR CRIME IS CHARGED
WITH A SERIOUS CRIME.
AND THERE IS A CATALOG OF CRIMES
THAT DO NOT ALLOW FOR BAIL.
THERE WAS SOME INDICATIONS TO
ARTICLE 19 OF THE MEXICAN
CONSTITUTION THAT ALLOW FOR BAIL
NOW, EXCEPT THAT SUPPOSEDLY,
SOME COURTS HAVE HELD THAT THAT
IS STILL NOT INTO EFFECT.
OTHER COURTS HAVE HELD THAT IT
HAS COME INTO EFFECT.
THAT'S A SERIOUS CONSTITUTIONAL
ISSUE.
MEANWHILE, TALKING ABOUT THE
JAIL, PARTICULARLY, HE WAS IN
THE GENERAL POPULATION, SOME
MONTHS AGO, FOR HIS WELL BEING,
THE U.S. CONSULATE, AS FAR AS I
UNDERSTAND, WAS ABLE TO MOVE HIM
TO AN ISOLATED PLACE BECAUSE
THIS JAIL THIS, PARTICULAR JAIL,
DOESN'T HAVE -- LET'S SAY LIKE
AN ISOLATED, SINGLE CELL FOR
PROTECTION.
THAT'S WHERE THEY HAVE HIM TO
PROTECT HIM FROM THREATS OR
WHATEVER.
>> GRETA: I FIND IT -- I KNOW
YOU ARE TRYING TO DO EVERYTHING
YOU CAN.
BUT HE IS A U.S. MARINE.
FROM WHAT I UNDERSTAND OF THE
FACTS, ARE THE FACTS THE CORRECT
FACTS?
THAT HE INFORMED THE U.S. AGENT
AT THE BORDER HE HAD THE ANTIQUE
GUN AND HEAVE -- HE WAS ON THE
WAY OUT OF THE COUNTRY AND THE
MEXICAN GOVERNMENT NOTIFIED HIM,
IS THAT WHAT HAPPENED?
>> 80%.
THE OTHER PART, A U.S. CUSTOMS
AGENT TOLD HIM IT WAS LEGAL TO
GO TO MEXICO WITH REGISTRATION
PAPERS.
THE PROBLEM WAS WHEN HE CAME
BACK INTO THE STATES.
HE GOES TO MEXICO WITH CUSTOMS
AND THEY TELL HIM TO WAIT AND
THEN FIVE HOURS LATER, HE WAS
ARRESTED FOR VIOLATION OF
ARTICLE 11, PARAGRAPH "H" OF THE
FEDERAL LAW OF WEAPONS AND
EXPLOSIVES, WHICH HAS THAT YOU
CAN IMPORT ANY SHOTGUN EXCEPT
CERTAIN TYPE OF SHOTGUNS.
FOR EXAMPLE, ONCE A CERTAIN
CALIBER.
THIS PARTICULAR CALIBER
WAS .410, WHICH IS NOT -- THIS
IS NOT RESERVED FOR THE
EXCLUSIVE USE OF THE ARMED
FORCES, AND NEITHER WERE THE
BULLETS, THE GAINS, THAT WAS FOR
THE NON-EXCLUSIVE.
THE ISSUE IS THE LEPT OF THE
BARREL, THAT'S THE PROBLEM --
HOW IT WAS MEASURED AND ALSO,
MOST IMPORTANT, THAT THAT -- LET
ME EXPLAIN TO YOU WHY -- IT WAS
NOT SAWED OFF.
AND THIS HAS TO BE UNDER 25
INCHES AND WE BELIEVE THE
MEASURE WAS TAKEN THE WRONG WAY
AND THAT'S WHAT WE ARE GOING TO
HEAMPL AT.
>> GRETA: I WISH YOU LUCK.
BUT, YOU KNOW, IT MAKES MY BLOOD
BOIL.
ALL SORTS OF INTERNATIONAL
TRADES ARE GOING FOR PRISONERS.
PAN AM 103, A KILLER OF 170
PEOPLE AND THERE WAS A SWAP FOR
HUMANITARIAN REASONS TO GO HOME
TO LIBYA.
WE HAVE A GUY WHO MAKES AN
INNOCENT MISTAKE WITH A GUN, A
U.S. MARINE AND THE U.S.
GOVERNMENT CAN'T FIND A SOLUTION
TO GET HIM HOME.
I AM VERY TROUBLED BECAUSE I
KNOW THIS GOES ON EVERY DAY OF
THE WEEK.
I HOPE OUR GOVERNMENT STEPS IN
AND GIVES YOU MORE HELP.
GOOD LUCK ON THIS.
>> I APPRECIATE.
LET ME TELL YOU, WE ARE DOING
EVERYTHING.
THERE IS A GROUP OF LAWYER, YOU
KNOW?
>> GRETA: I KNOW.
>> BELIEVE ME, WE ARE GOING TO
BRING JOHN HOME.
>> GRETA: I KNOW.
THERE ARE THINGS YOU DO IN THE
COURTROOM -- I KNOW YOU ARE
DOING EVERYTHING YOU CAN.
BUT THERE ARE THINGS THAT OUR
GOVERNMENT, OUR STATE DEPARTMENT
CAN DO.
WE CAN BE HEAVY HANDED TO
ACHIEVE THINGS ABOVE AND BEYOND
WHAT YOU ARE CAPABLE OF DOING IN
THE COURTROOM.
I HOPE YOU GET THAT EXTRA
HAPPEN.
THANK YOU.
>> I AGREE.
THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
I APPRECIATE IT.
>> GRETA: COMING UP, CONGRESSMAN
JASON CHAFITS, SAYING THE
GOVERNMENT IS HIDING BENGHAZI
SURVIVES.
AND A HANDBOOK, WARNING THAT
AMERICANS IN AFGHANISTAN NOT TO
INSULT
AMERICANS ARE ALWAYS READY TO
WORK HARD FOR A BETTER FUTURE.
SINCE AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL
WAS FOUNDED BACK IN 1894,
THEY'VE BEEN COMMITTED
TO PUTTING CLIENTS FIRST.
HELPING GENERATIONS
THROUGH TOUGH TIMES.
GOOD TIMES.
NEVER TAKING A BAILOUT.
THERE WHEN YOU NEED THEM.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
OVER THE CENTURIES.
THE STRENGTH OF
A GLOBAL FINANCIAL LEADER.
THE HEART OF
A ONE-TO-ONE RELATIONSHIP.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
>> GRETA: CONGRESSMAN ACCUSING
THE STATE DEPARTMENT OF HIDING
SURVIVORS OF AND WITNESSES TO
THE BENGHAZI TERROR ATTACK,
SAYING THE STATE DEPARTMENT
WON'T IDENTIFY WHO THEY ARE OR
GRANT ACCESS TO SURVIVOR WHO IS
ARE STILL IN THE HOSPITAL.
GOOD EVENING, SIR.
>> THANK YOU, GRETA.
>> GRETA: AS I HAVE DONE A
LITTLE MATHEMATICS.
IT LOOKS LIKE THERE WERE 20
AMERICANS EVACUATED FROM
BENGHAZI.
HAVE YOU HAD ACCESS TO ANY OF
THOSE 20 TO ASK THEM QUESTIONS
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED?
>> OH, NO.
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
NOW, WHEN I WENT TO LIBYA --
REMEMBER, I WENT TO TRIPOLI, I
WAS ABLE TO VISIT WITH
INDIVIDUALS WITH 1ST HAND
KNOWLEDGE.
WE ASKED NOT JUST ABOUT THE FOUR
PEOPLE WHO WERE INJURED INJURED,
WHO WAS INJURED, HOW MANY WERE
INJURED AND WHERE ARE THEY?
I HAVE ASKED THREE MAJOR
TELEVISION NETWORKS TO HELP ME
AND FOX NEWS AND PART OF THE BIG
NETWORK IT'S NONE OF THEM HAVE
BEEN GIVEN THIS INFORMATION.
IT'S BEEN TYPICAL WHEN WE HAVE
PEOPLE KILLED KILLED IN IRAQ,
AFGHANISTAN, THE NAMES ARE HELD
FOR MAYBE 48 HOURS, BUT WE DON'T
KNOW HOW MANY THEY ARE, WHO THE
FAMILIES ARE, WE WOULD LIKE TO
TALK TO THEM.
>> GRETA: AS A HOUSE REPUBLICAN,
YOU ARE IN THE MAJORITY PARTY,
WHY DON'T YOU DROP A SUBPOENA ON
SOMEONE AT THE STATE DEPARTMENT
TO SHOW UP AND ASK THAT PERSON
UNDER OATH WHO ARE THE PEOPLE
WHO WERE EVACUATED FROM
BENGHAZI?
AND WHERE ARE THEY?
>> BELIEVE ME, I AM A LITTLE BIT
FRUSTRATED THAT WE HAVE NOT BEEN
ISSUING SUBPOENAS.
WHAT WE ARE WAITING FOR, THOUGH,
IS THE STATE DEPARTMENT TO ISSUE
THEIR REPORT.
REMEMBER, THEY SAID THEY WEREN'T
GOING TO OFFER ANY INFORMATION
UNTIL THE BLUE RIBBON COMMISSION
WAS DONE.
THEY SAID THAT COULD TAKE 60 TO
65 DAYS, NOW THAT IT'S MON 3,
THEY OPOWE US A REPORT.
THAT'S I DIDN'T THINK SUSAN RICE
MADE THE ANNOUNCEMENT.
I THINK WE ARE THE VERGE OF
GETTING THE REPORT.
BUT THE STATE DEPARTMENT IS
SCWIRNLING, SAYING MAYBE WE WILL
GIVE YOU THE SUMMARY.
SECRETARY CLINTON MIGHT NOT COME
UP.
THE REPORT, IF DONE ACCURATELY,
IS GOING TO BE A VERY DIFFICULT
THING FOR THE WHITE HOUSE AND
THE STATE DEPARTMENT AND THE
DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE AND THE
CIA TO EXPLAIN.
I AM OPT MISTSIC, BUT I THINK
THAT'S WHY SUSAN RICE MADE THE
ANNOUNCEMENT TODAY.
IT IS ALREADY LATE.
>> GRETA: JUST TO FILL IN THE
BLANKS, THE ACCOUNTABILITY
REVIEW BOARD, WITHIN THE
DEPARTMENT OF THE STATE AND TOM
PICKERRING AND ADMIRAL MIKE
MULLEN ARE CONDUCTING THE
INVESTIGATION AND THE
EXPECTATION IS THAT ON DECEMBER
20, SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON WILL BE TESTIFYING ON
CAPITOL HILL BEFORE THE HOUSE
FOREIGN RELATIONS COMMITTEE AND
THE SENATE FOREIGN RELATIONS
COMMITTEE AND TALKING ABOUT THAT
REPORTS.
SO PRESUMABLY, IT WILL BE
COMPLETED BEFORE THEN.
BUT LATE TODAY, WE HAVE BEEN
HEARING NOISE THAT THE ENTIRE
REPORT WON'T BE RELEASED.
GO FIGURE.
THEY MAY CLAIM DLOIF CLASSIFIED
TOZE US, BUT I DON'T KNOW WHY
THE HOUSE AND THE SENATE
WOULDN'T GET THE FULL AND
COMPLETE REPORT.
>> IT'S EXACTLY RIGHT.
ONE OF THE CONCERNS WITH THOSE
WHO WERE INJURED IS HOW THEY
WERE EXTRACTED.
THE FIRE FIGHT STARTS AT 9:40
AND THE DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE
DOESN'T LEAVE GERMANY UNTIL 2:00
P.M. AND DOESN'T GET BACK UNTIL
THE 10:00 P.M. HOUR.
MEANWHILE -- NOBODY'S SAID THIS
ON TELEVISION, NOBODY'S
MENTIONED THIS -- THEY THOUGHT
THEY WERE GOING TO BE ATTACKED
IN TRIPOLI, THE EMBASSY WAS
EVACUATED IN TRIPOLI.
YET WHETHER THEY HAVE THE
INJURED PEOPLE ON THE TARMAC,
THEY ARE SEVERELY INJURED, THEY
SEND AN AIRPLANE OVER TO
BENGHAZI AND THEY RETURNED TO
TRIPOLI -- INSTEAD OF GOING TO
ITALY OR TO GERMANY -- THEN THE
C-17 HAS TO COME -- IT MAKES NO
SENSE.
IT MAKES ABSOLUTELY NO SENSE.
>> GRETA: THE IRONY AND I HAVE
NO SYMPATHY FOR THE
ADMINISTRATION'S CLAIMING THIS
IS POLITICIZED BECAUSE IF THEY
WOULD JUST SIMPLY ANSWER THESE
QUESTIONS, NOT DRAG THEIR FEET,
MAYBE WE WILL GET IT IN THE NEXT
6 OR 7 DAYS, BUT IF THEY WOULD
FILL IN THE BLANKS, NOBODY WOULD
BE SUSPICIOUS.
WE GET SILLY ANSWERS THAT DON'T
MAKE SENSE -- THAT'S THE
PROBLEM.
THAT IS CREATED BY THOSE WHO
HOLD THE FACTS.
>> THAT'S RIGHT!
I AM NOT TRYING TO POLITICIZE
THIS.
WE HAVE INJURED AMERICANS!
IN THE WORST CASE TTAKES 25
HOURS TO EXTRACT THEM TO A
FACILITY, AN AMERICAN FACILITY,
THEY'RE IN GERMANY.
AT THE BEST CASE, MAYBE 18 HOURS
AND THE ADMINISTRATION WON'T
ANSWER THOSE QUESTIONS.
THESE ARE LEGITIMATE QUESTIONS.
I WANT TO TALK TO THAT FAMILY.
THEY DESERVE TO HAVE ANSWERS.
WE HAVE TO MAKE SURE THIS NEVER,
EVER HAPPENS AGAIN.
WHEN AN AMERICAN GOES DOWN, WE
GO GET HIM.
THIS PRESIDENT DIDN'T DO THAT.
>> GRETA: IF YOU DON'T GET THE
ANSWERS NEXT WEEK,URE IN THE
MAJORITY PARTY, YOU HAVE THE
ABILITY TO DO IT.
YOU SHOULD ANY GO AHEAD AND DO .
YOU HAVE THE POWER TO GET THE
INFORMATION.
SO IF YOU COMPLAIN AND YOU DON'T
DO ANYTHING, YOU ARE
POLITICIZING IT.
>> I AM ARGUING WITH YOU THERE.
I AGREE WITH YOU.
>> GRETA: COMING UP, TABOO
TOPICS, THE PROPOSED ARMY
HANDBOOK, FORBIDDING U.S. TROOPS
TO INSULT THE TALIBAN, THAT
TALIBAN THAT INSULTS WOMEN.
THAT'S NOT ALL THAT THEY FORBID.
THAT'S NEXT.
AND IN TWO MINUTES, ULTIMATE
GOVERNMENT FIGHTING.
A PARLIAMENT SESSION, TUSHED
INTO A BARROOM BRAWL.
WHERE DID THIS HAPPEN?
AND HOW DID IT END?
I HAD ENOUGH OF FEELING
EMBARRASSED ABOUT MY SKIN.
[ Designer ]
ENOUGH OF JUST COVERING UP
MY MODERATE TO SEVERE
PLAQUE PSORIASIS.
I DECIDED ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
♪
[ Spa Lady ]
I STARTED ENBREL.
IT'S CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO PROVIDE CLEARER SKIN.
[ RV Guy ] ENBREL MAY NOT WORK
FOR EVERYONE --
AND MAY NOT CLEAR YOU
COMPLETELY,
BUT FOR MANY, IT GETS SKIN
CLEARER FAST, WITHIN 2 MONTHS,
AND KEEPS IT CLEARER
UP TO 9 MONTHS.
[ Male Announcer ]
BECAUSE ENBREL®, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL,
EVENTS INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS, LYMPHOMA,
OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING ENBREL,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START ENBREL IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON ENBREL, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING,
OR PALENESS.
IF YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH, ASK
YOUR DERMATOLOGIST ABOUT ENBREL.
>> GRETA: IF YOU THOUGHT MEMBERS
OF OUR CONGRESS DON'T GET ALONG,
CHECK THIS OUT.
UKRAINE LAWMAKERS IN A BENCH
LIFE CLEARING BRAWL IN A
PARLIAMENT SESSION, FIGHTS
BREAKING OUT TWO DAYS IN A ROW
IN THE GROUP'S OPENING SESSION.
THE GROUP GETTING OFF TO A
RATHER ROCKY START.
THE BATTLE IS BETWEEN THE
OPPOSITION AND THE MAJORITY
PARTIES.
THEY COULDN'T AGREE ON CHOOSING
A NEW SPEAKER, SO THIS IS HOW
THEY TRIED TO SETTLE THEIR
DIFFERENCES.
SCENES LIKE THIS ARE NOT UNUSUAL
IN THE UKRAINE.
IN RECENT YEARS, THERE HAVE BEEN
MANY PHYSICAL FIGHTS.
NOT SURE THIS IS THE BEST WAY TO
SETTLE POLICY DIFFERENCES.
BUT OUR GOVERNMENT DOESN'T SEEM
TO BE DOING MUCH BETTER.
ANY SUGGESTIONS FOR OUR
GOVERNMENT?
GO TO GretaWire AND WE ARE
BACK IN 90 SECONDS.
HAVING YOU SHIP MY GIFTS
COULDN'T BE EASIER.
WELL, HAVING A TON OF LOCATIONS
DOESN'T HURT.
AND A SANTA TO BOOT!
[ chuckles ]
RIGHT, BABY.
OH, SIR.
THAT IS A CUSTOMER.
OH...SORRY ABOUT THAT.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
FEDEX OFFICE.
TILL YOU FINISH YOUR VEGETABLES.
[ clock ticking ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THERE'S A BETTER WAY...
V8 V-FUSION.
VEGETABLE NUTRITION THEY NEED,
FRUIT TASTE THEY LOVE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
OR...TRY KIDS BOXES!
>> LIVE FROM AMERICA'S NEWS
HEADQUARTERS, I'M MARIANNE
RAFFERTY.
U.S. MILITARY EXPERTS SAY NORTH
KOREA IS YEARS FROM RELIABLE
MISSILES, DOES HE SPITE THIS
WEEK'S SUCCESSFUL ROCKET LAUNCH
THAT PUT A SATELLITE INTO ORBIT.
WHILE THE LAUNCH INDICATES
PROGRESS, IT DOESN'T MEAN
PYONGYANG HAS A SYSTEM THAT IS
MILLITARILY USEFUL.
NORTH KOREA WILL NEED LARGER
MISSILES AND MORE ADVANCED
NUCLEAR WEAPONS IN ORDER TO BE A
THREAT TO U.S. SHORES.
SECRETLY STALKING SOMEONE BY
USING CELL PHONE TRACKING APPs
COULD BECOME A THING OF THE
PAST.
THE SENATE JUDICIARY COMMITTEE
HAS A BILL TO PROTECT USERS FROM
HAVING SOMEONE ELSE FOLLOWING
THEIR EVERY MOVE, MAKING IT
ILLEGAL TO PRODUCE THE STALKING
APPs, AND IF THEY ARE USED,
THE COMPANY WOULD HAVE TO NOTIFY
THE PERSON BEING TARGETED.
NOW BACK TO "ON THE RECORD."
FOR YOUR LATEST HEADLINES, GO
TO foxnews.com.
foxnews.com.
>> GRETA: SO WHAT DO YOU THINK
ABOUT THE WARNINGS IN A PROPOSED
NEW HANDBOOK FOR AMERICANS
SERVING IN AFGHANISTAN?
THE PROPOSED GUIDELINES, TELLING
TROOPS NOT TO CRITICIZE THE
TALIBAN OR TO ADVOCATE FOR
WOMEN'S RIGHTS.
WHAT KIND OF RULES ARE THOSE?
AND WHAT MESSAGE DO THE RULES
SEND TO OUR TROOPS?
WE HAVE THE FIRST AMERICAN
FEMALE COMBAT PILOT WHO TOOK ON
THE DEFENSE DEPARTMENT FOR EQUAL
RIGHTS.
WHAT IS THE ARMY MANUAL?
>> IT'S A MANUAL THAT COMES OUT
OF THE CENTER FOR LESSONS
LEARNED FOR THE TROOPS BEING
GETTING READY TO TRAIN AND
DEPLOY TO AFGHANISTAN.
THE PROPOSED.
IT IS NOT FINAL.
BUT IT'S RIDICULOUS ON MANY
LEVELS.
>> GRETA: HERE'S PART OF IT FROM
ONE ARTICLE.
ONE OF THE CONFRONT EGGS
OCCUR -- WITH THE AFGHANIS, IS
BECAUSE OF COALITION -- THAT'S
US -- IGNORANCE OR OURE -- OUR
LACK OF EMPATHY FOR MUSLIM,
RESULTING IN VIOLENT REACTIONS
TOWARDS US.
>> THEY ARE TALKING ABOUT THE
GREEN-ON-BLUE ATTACK, WHERE THE
AFGHAN NATIONAL SECURITY FORCES
ARE TUSH TURNING ON OUR TROOPS
AND KILLING THEM.
THEY ARE KECKING THAT SOMEHOW
IT'S OUR TROOPS' BEHAVIOR, BEING
INSSENSITIVE TO THEM THAT IS
BRINGING ABOUT THEIR OWN
MURDERS.
THIS IS WRONG ON MANY LEVELS.
FIRST, THIS IS BLAMING THE
VICTIM, INSTEAD OF THE ACT OF
TERROR AND THE ACT OF MURDER.
THIS IS LIKE TELLING A RAPE
VICTIM, HER SKIRT WAS TOO SHORT.
THAT'S WRONG.
ON A SECOND LEVEL,ATS A METHOD
UNDERSTANDING OF THE
GREEN-ON-BLUE KILLINGS AND HOW
WE NEED TO BE ADDRESSING THEM.
THIRDLY, WE ARE ONCE AGAIN,
COMPROMISING OUR VALUES AS
AMERICANS AND PUTTING A LITTLE
CULTURAL SENSITIVITY ON OUR
TROOPS, CONFUSING THE ISSUE AND
MAKING OUR TROOPS NOW -- WHAT --
DON'T ADVOCATE FOR WOMEN'S
RIGHTS?
DON'T -- YOU KNOW, DON'T
CRITICIZE THE TALIBAN.
THERE IS --
>> GRETA: THEY DO SUCH HORRIBLE
THINGS TO WOMEN.
THEY ARE SUPPOSED TO STAND BY,
WE ARE SUPPOSED TO SAY, THAT'S
OKAY.
>> IT'S ABSOLUTELY INAPPROPRIATE
IRVEGHTS IT'S WORSE, IT'S WRONG.
>> VIOTHER WORDS.
I HAVE SEEN THIS IN MY CAREER,
IN MANY DIFFERENT TIMES, IT'S A
LITTLE CULTURAL SENSITIVITY IS
DANGEROUS AND LEADS TO STRATEGIC
BLUNDERS.
>> GRETA: MAYBE THEY NEED
CULTURAL SENSITIVITY THAT WE
HAVE WOMEN'S RIGHTS HERE.
MAYBE A LITTLE CULTURAL
SENSITIVITY TO US.
>> THE WHOLE IDEA OF BUILDING
PARTNER CAPACITY IS NOT TO
STRAIN THEM, BUT TO BE AN
EXAMPLE OF THEM -- OF WHAT WE
ARE LIKE, OUR PROFESSIONALISM,
OUR VALUES.
WE HAVE A PROBLEM WITH SEXUAL
HARASSMENT AND ASSAULT IN THE
MILITARY AND THE LEADERSHIP
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHAT IS THE
MATTER, IF YOU ARE COMING UP
WITH MANUALS THAT SAY DON'T
STAND UP FOR WOMEN'S RIGHT, IT
IS THOSE STATEMENTS ADDING TO
THE PROBLEM, EVEN IN THE U.S.
MILITARY.
>> GRETA: THE MANUAL SAYS, THERE
SHOULD BE NO PUBLIC CRITICISM OF
PEDID PED FEEL --
>> HOW DID THAT GET UP THE CHAIN
OF COMMAND.
>> GRETA: GENERAL JOHN ALLEN,
WHO HEADS THE FORCES, HE HAS
REJECTED THE MANUAL AND SAYS
IT'S A LOUSY IDEA.
>> THAT'S GOOD TO HEAR,
OBVIOUSLY.
BUT THIS IS THE ARMY THAT NEEDS
TO MAKE THEIR OWN DECISION TO
STOP THIS.
IT NEEDS TO BE, YOU KNOW,
STOPPED.
>> GRETA: STOPPED.
NICE TO SEE YOU.
>> NICE TO SEE YOU.
>> GRETA: A NEW CLIFF TO FALL
OFF, THE REGULATORY CLIFF.
WHAT IS THAT AND HOW DANGEROUS?
ARE WE HEADED OVER IT?
TRY RUNNING FOUR.NING
A RESTAURANT IS HARD,
FORTUNATELY WE'VE GOT INK.
IT GIVES US 5X THE REWARDS
ON OUR INTERNET, PHONE
CHARGES AND CABLE,
PLUS AT OFFICE SUPPLY STORES.
REWARDS WE PUT RIGHT
BACK INTO OUR BUSINESS.
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
WE'VE EVER WANTED TO DO
AND INK HELPS US DO IT.
MAKE YOUR MARK
WITH INK FROM CHASE.
>> GRETA: BRACE YOURSELF,
BESIDES HEADING OVER THE FISCAL
CLIFF, SOME PBS GROUPS ARE
WARRING ABOUT THE REGULATORY
CLIFF.
BYRON YORK IS HERE.
NICE TO SEE YOU.
WHAT IS THE REGULATORY CLIFF?
>> WELL, THE REGULATORY CLIFF IS
A BURVE OF REGULATIONS THAT HAVE
BEEN HELD UP FOR A WHILE THAT
ARE PROBABLY GOING TO COME OUT
OF THE OBAMA ADMINISTRATION
PRETTY SOON.
THE FEELING IS THAT THEY HAD A
LOT OF REGULATIONS, SOME OF
WHICH WOULD BE POLITICALLY
UNPOPULAR, THAT THEY HELD ON TO
UNTIL AFTER THE ELECTION.
ECONOMICALLY SIGNIFICANT
REGULATIONS, WHICH WOULD HAVE AT
LEAST $100 MILLION EFFECT ON THE
ECONOMY EVERY YEAR.
THE OBAMA ADMINISTRATION --
>> GOOD OR BAD.
>> WHATEVER.
I MEAN, IT'S SOMETHING THAT THE
CONGRESS WANTS TO KNOW IF YOU
ARE GOING TO DO THIS SIGNIFICANT
REGULATION, THE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION DID 63 OF THEM IN
2009.
63 IN 2010, 50 IN 2011 AND THEN
ABOUT 20 THIS YEAR.
>> GRETA: IS THAT BECAUSE THEY
HAVE DONE ALL THE ONES THEY
WANTED TO AND JUST OVER TIME,
THEY HAD NO MORE TO DO.
OR WAS THAT BECAUSE THEY WERE
TRYING TO HIDE THEM AND DO
POLITICAL MANEUVERING AND HOW DO
YOU TELL?
>> REPUBLICANS SAY THERE IS A
LOT OF THEM IN THE PIPELINE.
SO THEY WOULD -- THE VIEW THE
LATTER ANSWER.
THEY SAY THERE ARE A LOT OF THEM
IN THE PIPELINE.
THERE IS SOMETHING CALLED THE
UNIFIED AGENDA OF FEDERAL
REGULATIONS THAT THE
ADMINISTRATION IS REQUIRED TO
PUBLISH EACH YEAR IN THE SPRING
AND THE FALL AND THEY HAVEN'T
PUBLISHED EITHER ONE THIS YEAR.
THE REPUBLICANS ARE GETTING VERY
SUSPICIOUS,.
>> GRETA: IF THEY ARE REQUIRED
TO, WHY AREN'T THEY DOING IT?
I DON'T GET T. I AM REQUIRED TO
BE HERE AT 10:00 EVERY NIGHT.
SO I SHOW UP.
I DON'T GET IT.
>> WHY HASN'T SENATE PASSED A
BUDGET?
>> GRETA: HOW DO YOU GET THE
JOBS WHERE YOU HAVE REQUIREMENTS
THAT YOU DON'T HAVE TO DO?
HOW DO YOU GET THEM?
>> IT HELPS IF YOU GET ELECTED.
>> GRETA: I GUESS.
>> THEY HAVEN'T PUBLISHED THESE
THINGS.
THE REPUBLICANS THINK THERE WILL
BE A LOT OF REGULATIONS ON THE
ENVIRONMENT, THERE WILL BE VERY
COSTLY REGULATIONS ON RUNOFF IN
THE POLLUTION FROM COAL-FIRED
POWER PLANTS.
WE KNOW THERE IS GOING TO BE A
LOT OF REGULATIONS ABOUT
OBAMACARE THAT ARE COMING OUT --
>> GRETA: WE ARE GETTING THOSE.
>> EXACTLY!
WE TALKED ABOUT THE $63 A HEAD
LEVY THAT THE DEPARTMENT OF
HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES IS
PUTTING ON EVERY SINGLE PERSON
WHO HAS INSURANCE, CHARGING THE
INSURERS THAT.
WE KNOW THERE IS A LOT MORE
COMING OUT OF OBAMACARE BECAUSE,
OBVIOUSLY, THE EXCHANGES HAVE TO
BE UP AND RUNNING BY THIS FALL
AND THE WHOLE THING'S GOING TO
BE GOING BY JANUARY 1.
>> GRETA: IS THIS SOMETHING
OTHER ADMINISTRATIONS DID WHEN
THE SHOE WAS ON THE OTHER FOOT?
>> THE BUSH ADMINISTRATION DID A
LOT OF REGULATING.
THERE IS NO DOUBT ABOUT T. BUT
OBAMA HAS DONE MORE.
THE NUMBER OF ECONOMICALLY
SIGNIFICANT REGULATIONS HE HAS
DONE, HAS BEEN HIGHER THAN IN
PREVIOUS ADMINISTRATIONS.
AND SOME OF THIS IS PLAIN OLD
REPUBLICAN SUSPICION BECAUSE
THEY THINK THE PRESIDENT WAS
HOLDING BACK BEFORE THE
ELECTION, NOW THAT HE IS SAFELY
RE-ELECTED AND CAN'T RUN AGAIN,
NOW HE IS GOING TO LET IT OUT.
>> GRETA: WE ARE FINDING OUT
MORE ABOUT THE HEALTH CARE AND
THE FIGHTING IS GROWING.
>> THAT'S GOING TO BE HUGE.
>> GRETA: YOU ARE THE ONE WHO
TIPPED ME OFF TO THE 17 SENATOR
WHO IS WANT TO GET RID OF A TAX
THAT THEY VOTED FOR.
>> WHICH THEY VOTED FOR.
>> GRETA: WHICH THEY VOTED FOR.
NICE TO SEE YOU.
>> GOOD TO BE HERE.
>> GRETA: COMING UP, A BRAWL
BREAKING OUT IN A BASKETBALL
GAME.
BUT NOT THE PLAYERS.
THE CHAOS IS CAUGHT ON CAMERA.
YOU WILL SEEEEEEEEEE
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Sharable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
GOVERNOR OF GETTING IT DONE.
YOU KNOW HOW TO DANCE...
WITH A DEADLINE.
AND YOU...RENT FROM NATIONAL.
BECAUSE ONLY NATIONAL LETS YOU
CHOOSE ANY CAR IN THE AISLE...
AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE A FULL-SIZE
OR ABOVE,
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
THIS IS AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS, BUSINESS PRO.
YES, IT IS.
GO NATIONAL. GO LIKE A PRO.
GOIT 11:00 IS ALMOST HERE.
TIME FOR LAST CALL.
SPORTS RIVALRIES ARE HEATING UP.
LOOK AT THIS MASCOT MAYHEM.