Creamy cheese...
100 calories...
[ Chef ] Ma'am
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME R CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
>> THE GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT
IS REQUESTING ALL THE CHURCHES
IN THE STATE A WEEK AFTER THE
MASTER TO RING THE BELLS AND
REMEMBER.
THAT IS FOR IT "STUDIO B" WITH
JON SCOTT LATER TONIGHT ON THE
FOX REPORT.
>>Neil: THE FUNERALS HAVE
BEGUN AND THE SEVEN FOR WHY ALL
OF THIS HAPPENED, JUST GETTING
STARTED.
WELCOME,EN, I AM NEIL CAVUTO.
AS THE FIRST CHILDREN OF FRIDAY
MORNING'S CONNECTICUT SCHOOL
MASSACRE ARE LAID TO REST,
SCHOOL DISTRICTS AROUND THE
COUNTRY ARE DOING EVERYTHING
THEY CAN TO ALLAY PARENTS AND
STUDENTS OF THEIR FEAR BEEFING
YOU HAVE THEIR OWN EMERGENCY
DRILLS AND BENEFITING UP
SECURITY INCLUDING ARMED
SECURITY.
YES, GUARDS WITH GUNS AT SCHOOLS
THAT WANT THEM AND NEED THEM.
IN A MOMENT, THE FORMER HEAD OF
SECURITY FOR THE NEWTOWN SCHOOL
DISTRICT.
HE KNEW THE SHOOTER VERY WELL.
BUT, FIRST, TO RICK WITH THE
LATEST.
Rick: THIS IS A TOWN FULL OF
BROKEN HEARTS TODAY GOING THE
LONG AND DIFFICULT PROCESS OF
FUNERALS AND BURYING BEGINNING
WITH TWO SIX-YEAR-OLD BOYS.
JACK PINTO, A GIANTS FAN WITH
LOTS OF ENERGY AND DETERMINATION
, AND NOAH POZNER,
WHOSE TWIN SISTER SURVIVED.
IT MAY NEVER RE-OPEN AGAIN AS A
SCHOOL.
THAT IS TO BE DETERMINED.
MOVING VANS ROLLED UP AND HAULED
APPEAR THE DESKS AND CHAIRS AND
ARE RELOCATING THEM TO A FORMER
MIDDLE SCHOOL IN THE TOWN OF
MONROE SEVEN MILES AWAY WHERE
SANDY HOOK SURVIVORS WILL RESUME
THEIR CLASSES, POSSIBLY LATER
THIS WEEK.
WE ARE LEARNING MORE OF THE
20-YEAR-OLD SHOOT ARE DESCRIBED
AS A MERE GENIUS WHO TOOK
COLLEGE COURSES AT THE AGE OF
16, ALSO DESCRIBED AS SOCIALLY
AWKWARD AND STRUGGLING WITH AS
ASPERBER'S.
HE KILLED HIS MOTHER AND THEN
GUNNED DOWN TENTH -- 20 KIDS AND
SIX WOMEN.
HE HAD ENOUGH ROUNDS TO KILL
EVERY PERSON IN THE BUILDING BUT
KILLED HIMSELF AS THE POLICE
CLOSED IN.
NOW THEY ARE COMBING THROUGH THE
YOUNG MAN'S COMPUTER AND OTHER
POSSIBLE EVIDENCE AND
INTERVIEWING WITNESSES WHICH
WILL INCLUDE THE SURVIVING
CHILDREN.
>> I DON'T WANT TO USE THE
DETAILS OF THE TENDER ISSUE, AND
I CAN TELL YOU THAT ANY
INTERVIEWS WITH ANY CHILDREN
WILL BE DONE WITH PROFESSIONALS,
WITH PARENTS AND WITH
INVESTIGATORS AS APPROPRIATE.
THE INVESTIGATORS WILL DETERMINE
HOW, WHEN, WHERE AND WHY WE WILL
DO THIS.
>> THIS IS A COMMUNITY THAT IS
STILL REELING WITH VERY DARK AND
DIFFICULT DAYS AND WEEKS AHEAD.
>>Neil: THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
IN THE MEANTIME NEW CALLS TO ARM
EMPLOYEES AT SCHOOLS IN THE WAKE
OF THE SHOOTINGS THAT A FORMER
SECRET SERVICE AGENT SAYS COULD
SAVE LIVES.
MANY ARE TALKING SERIOUSLY ABOUT
THIS.
EASEEASIER SAID THAN DONE.
>> WOULD YOU RATHER A SITUATION
YOUR CHILD IS IN SCHOOL AND AN
AMENDED GUNMAN CONFRONTS SOMEONE
UNARMED OR ARMED.
WE ARE NOT TALKING ABOUT TURNING
THE SCHOOLS INTO ARMED CAMPS BUT
THERE IS A REASON WE HAVE ARMED
SECURITY GUARDS AT BANKS, THEY
ATTRACT AN ELEMENT THAT THE
BANGS DO NOT WANT.
UNFORTUNATELY, SCHOOLS HAVE NOW
BECOME A MAGNET FOR THIS TYPE OF
ACTIVITY.
>>Neil: I WONDER ABOUT OTHER
SCHOOLS WHERE THEY DID HAVE
PROCEDURES IN PLACE, INCLUDING
THIS ONE, BUZZING THE GUESTS IN,
AND ALL SORTS SAFETY SYSTEMS
THAT WOULD AT LEAST DETER BAD
GUYS FROM DOING SOMETHING.
IF YOU ARE LOADED FOR BEAR AND
YOU HAVE WEAPONS, THOSE SYSTEMS
ARE A MOOT POINT UNLESS YOU DO
ARM SOMEONE.
>>Guest: RIGHT, AND I DON'T
WANT TO OPEN UP A WOUND THAT IT
COULD BE SLOWLY STARTING TO HEAL
THIS IS DEVASTATING, BUT ARE WE
SERIOUS ABOUT SECURITY?
WHAT IS A BUZZING SYSTEM REALLY
DOING IF MOST OF THE
PERPETRATORS WHO COMMIT THE
CRIMES ARE PEOPLE KNOWN TO THE
SCHOOL THIS I PUT OUT A RELEASE
TODAY REGARDING A SERVICE, A
SECRET SERVICE STUDY IN
CONJUNCTION WITH THE DEPARTMENT
OF EDUCATION AND OVER
WOMENNINGLY THEY ARE --
OVERWHELMINGLY THEY ARE PEOPLE
NONE BY THE SCHOOLS.
THE SECRET SERVICE DOES THIS ALL
THE TIME, DISCREET SECURITY.
WHEN IS THE LAST TIME YOU SAW A
PRESIDENT WITH ARMED GUARDS.
BUT HE IS OUT OF THERE SAFE.
THERE ARE WAYS TO DO THIS.
>>Neil: WHAT ABOUT A SYSTEM IN
PLACE THAT TRIES TO MAKE SURE
THAT EVEN IF YOU KNOW PEOPLE,
YOU ARE SCREENING PEOPLE.
IN OTHER WORDS, WHETHER METAL
DETECTORS OR THE LIKE,
AUTHORITIES AT THE SCHOOL KNEW
THIS BOY, HE WAS A FORMER
STUDENT, AND, OF COURSE, FROM
EVERY INDICATION HE SHOT HIS WAY
IN THERE AND WHAT WE ARE TOLD
HAD HIS WAY, BUT, HOW DO YOU
MAKE SURE THAT EVEN THOSE WITH
WHOM YOU ARE FAMILIAR ARE
SCREENED?
>>Guest: WELL THE PROBLEM WITH
THE SCHOOL UNLIKE AN AIRPORT,
THE GOAL IN AN AIRPORT IS TO GET
TO A PLANE, THE GOAL OF THE
SCHOOL IS JUST TO GET IN THE
SCHOOL.
YOU WILL NOT SHOOT THE OPERATOR
OF THE EQUIPMENT AT THE AIRPORT,
BUT SOMEONE AT THE SCHOOL WILL
NOT GO THROUGH THE METAL
DETECTOR.
YOUR POINT IS VALID BUT WITH WE
HAVE TO LOOK AT IS WHAT WE CALL
AT THE SECRET SERVICE, HOW DO WE
HARDEN THEM UP?
WHEN SOMEONE IS COMMITTED AND
THEY ARE NOT GOING TO BE
STOPPED, THEY ARE BUZZED IN,
THEY HAVE ELIMINATED ANYONE IN
THEIR WAY AND THEY ARE THE
HALLWAY, WHAT DO WE DO TO HARDEN
THE CLASSROOM AND HOW DO WE MAKE
THE BIG SCHOOL, OR A BIG BOX A
SMALL BOX?
A LOT OF SECURE SMALL BOXES SO
THEY CAN HARDEN UP THE
CLASSROOMS AND YOU CAN BUY TIME.
IT IS ABOUT BUYING TIME.
TIME OF A PRECIOUS COMMODITY TO
ALLOW THE FIRST RESPONDERS AND
SPECIAL WEAPONS TEAMS TO
RESPOND.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
FORMER SECRET SERVICE AGENT.
>> AS A KID, ADAM LANZA STOOD
OUT IT IS SAID.
A FIRM SECURITY DIRECTOR WHO
KNEW HIM WELL AND WORRIED ABOUT
HIM EVEN MORE.
SAVORY GARLIC SHR.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
AND I'M HERE TO TELL HOMEOWNERS
THAT ARE 62 AND OLDER
ABOUT A GREAT WAY
TO LIVE A BETTER RETIREMENT.
IT'S CALLED A REVERSE MORTGAGE.
[ Male Announcer ]
CALL RIGHT NOW
TO RECEIVE YOUR FREE
DVD AND BOOKLET
WITH NO
OBLIGATION.
IT ANSWERS QUESTIONS LIKE
HOW A REVERSE MORTGAGE WORKS,
HOW MUCH YOU QUALIFY FOR,
THE WAYS TO RECEIVE YOUR MONEY,
AND MORE.
PLUS, WHEN
YOU CALL NOW,
YOU'LL GET THIS MAGNIFIER
WITH L.E.D. LIGHT
ABSOLUTELY FREE.
WHEN YOU CALL THE EXPERTS
AT One Reverse Mortgage TODAY,
YOU'LL LEARN THE BENEFITS
OF A GOVERNMENT-INSURED
REVERSE MORTGAGE.
IT WILL ELIMINATE
YOUR MONTHLY MORTGAGE PAYMENTS
AND GIVE YOU TAX-FREE CASH
FROM THE EQUITY IN YOUR HOME.
AND HERE'S THE BEST PART --
YOU STILL OWN YOUR HOME.
TAKE CONTROL
OF YOUR RETIREMENT TODAY.
♪
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>>Neil: YEARS BEFORE HE
BECAME A KILLER, A LOANER.
QUIET.
MY NEXT GUEST REMEMBERS ADAM
LANZA IN HIGH SCHOOL, HE WAS AN
ADVISOR FOR THE SCHOOL
TECHNOLOGY CLUB WHICH HE WAS A
MEMBER.
HE KNEW HIS MOTHER, AS WELL.
ALSO, HE IS HEAD OF SECURITY FOR
THE NEWTOWN SCHOOL DISTRICT AND
HE COULD NEVER HAVE SEEN THIS
COMING WITH THIS PARTICULAR
YOUNG MAN.
MAYBE YOU CAN TELL US A LITTLE
BIT ABOUT THE YOUNG ADAM WE MAY
NOT KNOW.
YOU KNEW HIM IN HIGH SCHOOL AND
IN THIS CLUB.
ANY RECOLLECTIONS?
>>Guest: HE WAS A VERY QUIET
BOY.
VERY SMALL.
THIN.
FRAIL.
GENTLE.
LOVING.
CARING.
BUT WITHDRAWN AND POOR SOCIAL
KILLS.
HARD A HARD TIME INTERACTING
WITH EVERYONE INCLUDING OTHER
TEENAGERS.
>>Neil: WAS HE PICKED ON?
>>Guest: NO.
ONE THING WE MADE SURE OF HE WAS
NOT.
I HAVE BEEN ASKED THAT QUESTION
BEFORE AND THE ENTIRE TIME THAT
I KNEW HIM, ELEMENTARY THROUGH
HIGH SCHOOL, I CAN ASSURE YOU HE
WASN'T.
HE COULD HAVE BECOME A VICTIM
AND THAT IS WHY HE HAD SO MUCH
CARE GIVEN TO HIM.
>>Neil: WHAT DID THE
TECHNOLOGY CLUB DO?
>>Guest: VIDEO PRODUCTION.
WE RAN A LOCAL ACCESS NETWORK,
EDUCATIONAL NETWORK.
WE REPUBLICAN A RADIO STATION
THROUGH THAT SAME NETWORK.
WE WENT TO THE TOWN PEOPLE IN
THE DIRECT AND THROUGH CABLE
NETWORK SO WE DID VIDEO
PRODUCTION ON A LARGE SCALE, NOT
AS BIG AS HERE BUT IT WAS A LOT
OF FUN AND IT DREW IN A LOT OF
CHILDREN THAT LOVED TECHNOLOGY
SO TECHNOLOGY, TODAY, INCLUDES
VIDEO PRODUCTION ON COMPUTER
SOFTWARE AND ED SITTING -- ED
SITTING BOARDS AND CABLE WIRING
AND LIGHTING ISSUES.
HE WAS INVOLVED IN ALL OF THAT.
>>Neil: WAS HE GOOD AT IT?
>>Guest: HE WAS GOOD AT IT.
HE WAS ENCOURAGED TO COME UP TO
THE HIGH SCHOOL THROUGH A
PROGRAM THAT WAS PUT IN PLACE
WHERE WE WOULD GO TO THE MIDDLE
SCHOOL LOOKING FOR RECRUITS THAT
WOULD BE COMING TO THE HIGH
SCHOOL AND THAT IS MY FIRST
INTERACTS WOULD HAVE BEGUN WITH
ADAM.
>>Neil: YOU KNEW HIS MOTHER.
>>Guest: I DID.
>>Imus: HE WOULD HAVE A LOT OF
CONCERN, YOURS AND OTHERS,
EXPRESSED ABOUT NOT HIS BEHAVIOR
BUT HIS RECLUSIVENESS, AND THE
MOTHER WOULD COME TO THE SCHOOL
TO ADDRESS THEM WITH THE SCHOOL
AUTHORITIES, OR WHAT, EXACT
HAPPEN?
>>Guest: YES, I HAVE SAID MORE
LIKE AN EPISODE WHERE HIS
CONDITION WORSENED AND HE
WITHDREW INTO HIMSELF.
IN OTHER WORDS, HIS INABILITY TO
COMMUNICATE WOULD GET WORSE OR
TO SHARE WHAT HE WAS FEELING
WOULD BE WORSE.
MRS. LANZA WAS A WONDERFUL
PARENT WHO OFTEN WAS ON CAMPUS
FOR HER SON.
>>Neil: NOW THE PARENT WOULD
HAVE BEEN DIVORCED AT THIS TIME.
SO HE WAS LIVING WITH HIS MOM AT
THIS TIME, IS THAT CORRECT?
>>Guest: WHICH TIME?
>>Neil: WHEN HE WAS IN HIGH
SCHOOL?
>>Guest: NO, HIS FAMILY WAS
TOGETHER.
>>Neil: THEY WERE TOGETHER AT
THAT TIME.
>>Guest: MY BELIEVE IS THEY
WERE, YES.
THEY MAY HAVE BEEN GOING, THEY
WERE SHOWING SIGNS OF FAMILY
DYSFUNCTION AS FAR AS BETWEEN
THE HUSBAND AND WIFE THAT THE
CHILDREN THAT COMES OUT IN A
SCHOOL SETTING AND SOME MAY SAY
THEY ARE NOT DOING THE MATH OR
ENGLISH AND WHY YOUR GRADES GO
FROM 90'S TO F AND A LOT OF KIDS
SHOW THAT WITH A DIVORCE OR
DIFFICULTY IN THE HOME.
THERE WAS SOME TALK AND YOU CAN
SENSE IF YOU ARE THAT CLOSE TO
THE KIDS, WHAT IS GOING ON, IT
COULD BE RELATED TO HOME.
HOWEVER, I WOULD LIKE TO POINT
OUT THAT BEING AT THE HIGH
SCHOOL THAT MANY HOURS INVOLVED
IN A TECHNOLOGY CLUB IS THEIR
SAFETY ZONE.
THEY CAN BE AWAY FROM HOME WHERE
THE PROBLEMS ARE, THEY NOT ON
THE STREETS.
THEY ARE IN THE SCHOOL SYSTEM
WITH WONDERFUL ADMINISTRATOR AND
SUPPORT GROUPS AND SECURITY AT
THEIR SIDE, RUNNING AROUND DOING
ALL KINDS OF FUN ACTIVISTS SO IT
WOULD BE A PLACE WHERE ADAM
WOULD HAVE FOUND A RELEASE FROM
ANYTHING THAT WAS DISTURBING
HIM.
>>Neil: REMAIN OTHER STUDENTS
SCARED OF HIM?
>>Guest: NO ONE WAS SCARED OF
HIM.
HE WAS THE TYPE THAT WE HAD TO
WORRY ABOUT BEING VICTIMIZED.
THE TECH CLUB ENVIRONMENT WHICH
HE WAS OFTEN INVOLVED IN, WHERE
WE SPENT OUR TIME TOGETHER, WAS
AN ENVIRONMENT COMPRISED OF VERY
INTELLECTUAL-MINED KIDS HIGH ON
THE BELL CURVE, LOVING, WELL
RAISED, WELL RESPECTED, A LOST
RESPECT FOR ADULTS AND PEERS THE
GEEKY TYPE.
I AM SMILING BECAUSE I THINK
THAT IS A WONDERFUL THING.
THEY ADOPTED HIM NAUGHTON LIKE
YOU WOULD ADOPT ANY NEW FRESHMAN
COMING IN BUT WE UNDERSTOOD HE
NEEDED A LITTLE BIT EXTRA
OBSERVATION.
>>Neil: WHAT YOU KNEW OF THE
MOM, DOES SHE EVERY LAY TO YOU
CONCERN OR A CHILD THAT DOES NOT
SEEM TO BE CONNECTING BEING
PART OF THE SCHOOL?
>>Guest: I CAN MAKE IT CLEAR
THAT IF MY POSITION AS A
DIRECTOR OF SECURITY, THE TYPE
OF PERSON IN THIS CASE THAT
DECIDED TO BE ON THE GROUND EACH
DAY RATHER THAN SITTING IN AN
OFFICE, AS WELL AS A PERSON WHO
WOULD BE SPENDING A LOT OF TIME
ON HER SON IN ACTIVITY
ON-AND-OFF CAMPUS AND ON THE
FOOTBALL FIELDS, MRS. LANZA AND
I DID DISCUSS ADAM'S CONDITIONS
AND SPECIAL NEEDS.
I, TOO, REACHED OUT AND FOUND
OUT MORE AND WE HAD MEETINGS
USED EARLY WHEN ADAM CAME TO
SCHOOL WITH PSYCHOLOGISTS AND
AIDES AND GUIDANCE COUNSELORS.
HE WAS AFFORDED TALENTED AND
GOOD SERVICES TO ENSURE THAT TO
SOME TOGETHER HE WOULD BE MORE
SUCCESSFUL EACH DAY HE WAS THIS.
>>Neil: THANK YOU, RICHARD, WE
APPRECIATE THAT.
THIS WERE WARNING SIGNS, DID
LEGAL LIMITS PREVENT SCHOOL
AUTHORITIES FROM PURSUING THEM?
IT'S KIND OF LIKE DRINKING
A FOOD THAT'S A DRINK,
OR A DRINK THAT'S A FOOD,
WOOOOOH!
[ Male Announcer ] TASTE IT
AND DESCRIBE THE INDESCRIBABLE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
>> IT WAS EVER ACCIDENT TO ME
THERE WAS RELUCTANCE TO TELL
PARENTS AND LOVED ONES THAT THE
PERSON THEY WERE WAITING FOR WAS
NOT GOING TO RETURN.
THAT HAD GONE ON FOR A PERIOD OF
TIME WELL AFTER THERE WAS ANY
EXPECTANCY THAT FAMILIES WOULD
BE REUNITED.
>>Neil: REMARKS FROM GOVERNOR
MALLOY OF CONNECTICUT WHAT HAD
TO BE UNBEARABLE GRIEF FOR
PARENT WHOSE ARRIVED AT THE
SCHOOL ON FRIDAY ONLY TO FIND
OUT THEIR CHILD WAS NOT AMONG
THOSE COMING OUT OF THE SCHOOL.
HOW MUCH COULD WE HAVE KNOWN?
HOW MUCH COULD WE HAVE DONE?
HOW MUCH COULD BE TELEGRAPHED TO
AVOID THIS?
WE HAVE A PSYCHO THERAPIST AND
ATTORNEY AND SECURITY EXPERT.
AS A SECURITY GUY WHAT DO YOU DO
WHEN YOU KNOW THERE IS CONCERN
ABOUT A PARTICULAR YOUNG MAN WHO
SEEMED EVEN IN THE LAST SEGMENT
AS A YOUNG STUDENT, TO HAVE
RELAYED ODD BEHAVIOR, BUT
NOTHING MORE, JUST ODD BEHAVIOR.
>>Guest: I HATE TO SAY THIS
BUT WE HAVE BAD PEOPLE IN THIS
WORLD AND EVIL PEOPLE IN THIS
WORLD WHO WILL DO BAD THINGS AT
TIMES NO MATTER WHAT THE WARNING
SIGNS ARE AND IN THIS CASE THERE
WASN'T MUCH OH THAN HE DID NOT
FIT IN, IN THE CLASS ROOM, HE
SEEMED A LITTLE BIT ODD.
BUT THERE IS NOTHING THERE THAT
LAW ENFORCEMENT COULD HAVE DONE
OR WOULD HAVE PROBABLY FORESEEN
THAT WE KNOW ABOUT SO FAR.
>>Neil: WE COULD GO THE OTHER
WAY IN AN ENVIRONMENT AND YOU
COULD LOOK AT IT AND SAY, WELL,
WE DON'T WANT TO GO ON A WITCH
HUNT, DO WE?
>>Guest: YOU CANNOT GO ON A
WITCH HUNT FOR ODD KIDS.
EVEN IN ORDER TO GET HIM IN
VOLUNTARY OUTPAINT TREATMENT
WHICH HAS BEEN SUGGESTED, YOU
WOULD HAVE TO GO TO COURT AND
GET A COURT ORDER AND GET A
JUDGE DO SAY, YES, YOU WILL NOW
FORCE THIS PERSON TO TAKE
MEDICATION AND TO SEE A
THERAPIST BUT IN THIS PARTICULAR
CASE, WHO WOULD HAVE DONE THAT?
IT ISN'T THAT HE THREATENED
ANYONE IN ADVANCE OR THAT HE WAS
AN ACTIVE STUDENT IN A SCHOOL
WHERE HIS TEACHER COULD HAVE
SAID, OKAY, THIS CHILD IS VERY
STUBBED AND HE IS MAKING THREATS
AND WE ARE AFRAID OF HIM.
>>Neil: HE DID NOT MAKE ANY
THREATS HE WAS MORE A POTENTIAL
SUBJECT OF BULLYING, SO, DOCTOR,
WHAT ARE WE OBLIGATED TO DO?
IT SOUNDS LIKE THE SYSTEM THERE
DID AS MUCH AS IT COULD BE
REQUIRED TO DO FROM PSYCHOLOGIST
TO BRINGING THIS INTROVERTED
NATURE TO THE MOM'S ATTENTION.
>>Guest: IT SOUNDS LIKE WHEN
HE WAS IN SCHOOL SOMETHING ABOUT
THE SCHOOL STRUCTURE WAS HEALING
AND KEEPING HIM TOGETHER AND NOW
HE IS A KID WHO IS IN HIS 20'S
LIVING IF HIS MOTHER'S HOME AND
HE IS NOT WORKING SO THERE IS A
DISABILITY THERE, YOU HAVE AN
INTELLECT CHILD WHO IS ISOLATED.
THIS IS WHERE WE NEED TO LIFT
THE STIGMA OF MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES AND ENCOURAGE FAMILIES
WHO ARE WORRIED ABOUT THEIR
CHILDREN EVEN IF THEY ARE ADULTS
AND DIRECT THEM TO THE
APPROPRIATE PLACES TO GET HELP.
WE CANNOT ALWAYS PREDICT VIOLENT
BEHAVIOR.
WE DO LIVE IN AN UNPREDICTABLE
WORLD.
IF WE DO ENCOURAGE FAMILIES TO
NOT HANDLE THINGS ALONE AND TO
REACH OUT TO PEOPLE IN THE
COMMUNITY WHO CAN HELP, PERHAPS
THINGS LIKE THIS WOULD BE LESS
LIKELY TO HAPPEN.
>>Neil: YOU THINK ABOUT IT HE
WAS OUT SCHOOL A WHILE AT 20
YEARS OLD AND NEVERTHELESS, A
LOT OF PEOPLED THINK THEY SHOULD
HAVE NOTICED MORE THE HOW DO YOU
HANDLE IT IF YOU HAVE KIDS AND
YOU KNOW THEIR FRIENDS AND YOU
ARE NOT SURE ABOUT IT, WHERE DO
YOU DRAW THE LINE?
>>Guest: YOU DRAW THE BEHIND
AT WHAT IS LEGAL.
YOU HAVE TO ACT IN THE LAW, FROM
LAW ENFORCEMENT STANDPOINT.
CAN YOU NOT EXCEED THAT.
>>Neil: WHAT DOES THE LAW SAY
IF YOU HAVE NO PRIOR HISTORY OF
VIOLENCE OR BAD BEHAVIOR, ACTING
VIOLENTLY DOES NOT CUT IT.
>>Guest: THIS IS A NATIONAL
DISCUSSION AND WE HAVE TO LOOK
TO THAT, OF HOW WE WILL TELL
WITH PEOPLE WHO ARE NOT FALLING
IN OUR SOCIETY.
WHAT ARE WE GOING TO DO?
WHAT CAN LAW ENFORCEMENT DO?
WHAT AND CAN PSYCHOLOGISTS AND
LAWYERS DO DO MAKE THE
DISCUSSION COME TO FRUITION TO
MONITOR THE PEOPLE WITH WE HAVE
SEEN IN THE LAST SIX MONTHS OR A
YEAR COME FORWARD AND CAUSE
VIOLENT ACTS AS WELL AS TRAGEDY.
>>Neil: WHAT IF THEY GET
THROUGH HIGH SCHOOL JUST FINE,
OR COLLEGE, AND HE DROPPED OUT
AND THEY ARE OUT IN SOCIETY AND
THEN WHAT?
>>Guest: SOMEONE PRESENTS
THEMSELVES AS A DANGER.
>>Neil: BUT NOTHING
TELEGRAPHED THAT.
>>Guest: NO, READING BETWEEN
THE LINES CAN YOU NOT GO TO THE
JUDGE AND SAID, THIS GUY IS
WEIRD WE WANT HIM TO TAKE
MEDICATION.
>> YOU ARE READING BETWEEN THE
LINES.
>> YOU HAVE TO HAVE A PERSON
THAT WILL DO THAT.
IN THIS CASE, FROM WHAT WE KNOW,
HE STAYED IN HIS HOUSE AND HIS
MOTHER IS THE ONE THAT IS
TEACHING HIM HOW TO USE THE GUNS
SHE IS NOT GOING TO SAY, OKAY,
MY SON IS STUBBED, LET'S GIVE
HIM MEDICATION.
>> SHE SHOULD BE.
SHE SHOULD IS SAID, MY SON, I AM
STRUGGLING HERE AND I DIDN'T
HEAR THAT.
ALSO, IT IS THE ONLY TIME HER
SON WAS FEELING GOOD IN SOCIETY
AND STRONG AND VIRILE IS WHEN
SHE IS TEACHING HIM WHO TO USE
GUNS SHE IS TRAINING HIM TO BE A
KILLER AND WE MAY NOT WANT TO
SAY THAT.
>>Guest: WE DON'T KNOW WHAT
WAS HAPPENING PRIVATELY IN THE
HOUSE.
THE FORENSICS OF OF THE HARD
DRIVE MAY TELL US MORE.
WE KNOW SHE WAS, THE TALK IS SHE
WAS LOOKING FOR A SCHOOL OR A
PLACE TO SEND HIM.
WHY IF BECAUSE HE WAS STARTING
TO ACT OUT AT HOME?
MAYBE IT WAS HER RESPONSIBILITY
THEN TO BRING IT FORWARD TO LAW
ENFORCEMENT OR PSYCHIATRIST OR A
LAWYER TO THEN TAKE THE
APPROPRIATE ACTS TO GET HIM
COMMITTED AND GET HIM THERAPY.
>>Neil: AND TEACHING SOMEONE
DOES NOT MAKE YOU A KILLER.
>>Guest: BUT IT IS DISTURBED.
>>Neil: IT RAISES AN ISSUE
FROM WHAT I HEARD ABOUT THE
MOTHER SHE WAS REPEATEDLY AT THE
SCHOOL DEALING WITH COUNSELORS
KNOWING THERE WERE ISSUES WITH
HER SON BUT THAT IS NOTHING
PARENTS WANT TO HEAR L IS SOME
CRAZY KID WATCHING THIS
COVERAGE, WATCHING THIS NATIONAL
OBSESSION WITH WHAT HAPPENED IN
THIS DOWN, AND PLOTTING PROBABLY
SOMETHING VERY SIMILAR.
>>Guest: IF YOU ARE PLOTTING
SOMETHING LIKE THIS, YOU COULD
NOT FORCE THEM TO GO TO THERAPY
AND YOU CAN HAND THEM A BATTLE
OF PILLS BUT YOU CANNOT FORCE
THE PILLS DOWN THEIR LET.
IF SOMEONE IS SICK ENOUGH THEY
ARE GOING TO GIVE THEIR OWN HIVE
IN ORDER TO DO SOMETHING
HORRIFIC LIKE WHAT HAPPENED
HERE, THERE IS NOTHING YOU CAN
DO.
>>Neil: SO ALL THE GUN LAWS
AND ALL THE SECURITY MEASURES
THE SCHOOLS ARE TAKEN, IF
SOMEONE IS INTENT ON DOING
SOMETHING, REALLY DASTARDLY.
>>Guest: IF SOMEONE VIOLATE AS
COURT ORDER IF THEY ARE INTENT
ON DOING THIS.
>>Guest: IT COULD HAPPEN, BUT,
IF THAT IS HAPPENING AND IF
SOMEONE IS OUT THERE AND SOMEONE
KNOWS ABOUT IT, THEY SHOULD CALL
LAW ENFORCEMENT BECAUSE LAW
ENFORCEMENT AND LAWYERS AND
PSYCHIATRISTS CAN DO SOMETHING
FOR THAT INDIVIDUAL AND
POTENTIALLY STOP A DENVER OR
CONNECTICUT FROM HAPPENING.
>>Guest: AND WE CAN MAKE IT
POSSIBLE FOR YOUNG MEN TO FEEL
GOOD ABOUT THEMSELVES WITHOUT
NEEDING TO GO ON A SPREE-KILLING
RAGE.
WE NEED TO LOOK AT OUR SOCIETY.
WE DON'T KNOW THE ANSWER TO
THAT.
>>Neil: THE VICTIMS' PARENTS,
THEY ARE ENRAGED AND LOOKING FOR
SOMEONE TO BLAME.
WHO?
>>Guest: THAT IS TOUGH.
>> NO ONE TO BLAME.
SOMETIMES AS WE TALK ABOUT, YOU
GO TO NORWAY, YOU GO TO THE GUY
WHO WENT OVER THE ISLAND AND
SHOT UP THE ISLAND KILLING ALL
THOSE YOUNG PEOPLE, SOMETIMES
THERE IS IN EXPLANATION.
SOMETIMES OVERVILLE HAPPENS AND
TRAGEDIES DO HAPPEN WITHOUT --
WE WANT AN ANSWER BUT SOMETIMES
THERE IS NO ANSWER.
>> WE NEED TO FIND OUT WHAT IS
CAUSING THIS TREND.
THE TRUTH IS WE DON'T KNOW.
WE NEED TO FIND OUT.
>>Neil: THANK YOU.
IN THE MEANTIME, A FISCAL CLIFF
DEAL?
NOT QUITE, BUT INTERESTING, A
DAY AFTER TALKING IN NEWTOWN
ABOUT A COUNTRY COMING TOGETHER,
THE PRESIDENT AND SPEAKER
BOEHNER ON A DEAL SOME THOUGHT
WAS FALLING APART.
MAYBE NOT.
>> HOURS AFTER GETTING
BIPARTISAN HELP CONNECTICUT,
BIPARTISANSHIP WITH PRESIDENT
AND SPEAKER BOEHNER MEETING IN
PERSON TODAY AT WHITE HOUSE EACH
WITH INTERESTING COMPROMISES ON
THE TABLE INCLUDING THE
SPEAKER'S REPORTED WILLINGNESS
TO LET TAX RATES RISE FOR THOSE
MAKING $1 MILLION OR MORE AND
TYING A DEAL TO A POSSIBLE HIKE
IN THE DEBT CEILING.
IN RETURN THE PRESIDENT SHOWING
MORE FLEXIBILITY ON ENTITLEMENT
SPENDING.
HOW MUCH IS STILL VERY UNCLEAR.
AND NOW, WHAT DO WE MAKE OF THE
DEVELOPMENTS AND WHETHER WHAT
HAPPENED IN CONNECTICUT IS WHAT
IS SPURRING THEM ON?
>>Guest: I THINK THAT IS A
GOOD POINT.
YES, I DO THINK THEY ARE GETTING
CLOSER TO A BIPARTISAN
COMPROMISE IN LIGHT OF THE
TRAGEDY.
THE WHITE HOUSE AND SPEAKER
BOEHNER'S OFFICE ARE FOUGHT
GIVING DETAILS ABOUT THE MEETING
THE SPEAKER BOEHNER AND THE
PRESIDENT HAD.
I HAVE THE SENSE THAT DEMOCRATS
ARE MORE OPTIMISTIC IN THE
OUTCOME.
SPEAKER BOEHNER'S OFFICE IS
SAYING THAT T DON'T
THINK THAT PRESIDENT OBAMA IS AS
SERIOUS AS THEY WOULD LIKE TO
SEE HIM ON SPENDING CUTS.
THE WHITE HOUSE TELLS ME THE
LINES OF COMMUNICATION ARE OPEN
AND THEY ARE STILL NEGOTIATING
BUT THE DEMOCRATS THING A DEAL
IS CLOSER NOW THAN REPUBLICANS
DO.
>>Neil: OBVIOUSLY THEY AWARE
IN THIS ENVIRONMENT YOU DO
THOUGHT WANT TO LOOK LIKE YOU
ARE POINTING FINGERS AND COME
MAINING.
THAT MAKES IT INCUMBENT UPON THE
REPUBLICANS AND THE DEMOCRATS TO
LOOK LIKE THEY ARE TRYING, WHICH
COULD EXPLAIN WHY, TODAY, THEY
WOULD BE DEALING?
>>Guest: THEY DON'T WANT TO BE
POINTING FINGERS AT EACH OTHER
AND THEY WANT DID GET A DEAL
DONE AND THEY DON'T WANT TO HEAR
A LOT OF CRITICISM FROM THEIR
BASE.
WE HAVE SEEN THE CLUB FOR GROWTH
AND TEA PARTY GROUPS ARE
CRITICIZING SPEAKER BOEHNER FOR
THIS IDEA HE IS WILLING TO GIVE
ON TAX RATES BUT THEY DON'T WANT
TO HEAR THE COMPLAINTS.
AS WE GO TO THE NEXT WEEK, WE
WILL HEAR MORE FROM 9D BASE
BECAUSE THEY DON'T WANT TO SEE
THE PRESIDENT GIVE UP MORE ON
SPENDING CUTS OR ENTITLEMENT
REFORM SO A LOT OF THIS IS GOING
ON BEHIND CLOSED DOORS AND WE
ARE NOT GIVING THEM THE DETAILS.
>>Neil: WHAT DO YOU THINK WENT
ON AT THE MEETING IN OBVIOUSLY
IT IS HOURS AFTER THE PRESIDENT
SPOKE LAST NIGHT IN CONNECTICUT.
WHAT DO YOU THINK HAPPENED.
>>Guest: RIGHT NEW THEY
FIDDLING WITH THE AMOUNT OF
REVENUE THEY CAN RAISE IF THIS
DEAL.
WE SAW SPEAKER BOEHNER PUT FORTH
$800 IF RAISING REVENUE.
DOUSE THE WHITE HOUSE SAID THAT
WASN'T ENOUGH WITH THE FIRST
PROPOSAL AT $1.6 TRILLION AND
THE PRESIDENT CAME DOWN TO $1.4
TRILLION LAST WEEK AND NOW THEY
TRYING TO COME UP WITH A
COMPROMISE ON THE AMOUNT OF
REVENUE THEY CAN RAISE.
THAT IS WHAT THEY ARE TRYING TO
SETTLE ON BEFORE THEY TALK
SPENDING CUTS.
>>Neil: HOW IRONIC THAT WOULD
BE, IT TAKE AS TRAGEDY TO GET US
OFF THE CLIFF.
WE WILL SEE.
THANK YOU.
DO YOU ASK, HOW COULD GOD LESS
THIS HAPPEN?
HOW MANY TIMES HAVE YOU HEARD
FOLKS AROUND THE COUNTRY ASK
THAT QUESTION AGAIN AND AGAIN
SINCE THIS HORROR?
THAT IS NEXT.
ADE.
SO WE HAVE ONGOING WEBINARS
AND INTERACTIVE LEARNING,
PLUS, IN-BRANCH SEMINARS
AT OVER 500 LOCATIONS,
WHERE OUR DEDICATED SUPPORT
TEAMS HELP YOU KNOW MORE
SO YOUR MONEY CAN DO MORE.
[ Rodger ] AT SCOTTRADE,
SEVEN DOLLAR TRADES
ARE JUST THE START.
OUR TEAMS HAVE THE
INFORMATION YOU WANT
WHEN YOU NEED IT.
IT'S ANOTHEREASON
MORE INVESTORS ARE SAYING...
[ All ]
I'M WITH SCOTTRADE.
they see more than themselves.
MORElook in the mirror,NG...
So we celebrate our year-end
with the "share the love" event.
Get a great deal on a new Subaru
and 250 dollars goes to your
choice of five charities.
By the end of this, our fifth
year,
our total can reach almost 25
million dollars.
It's a nice reflection on us
all.
Now through January 2nd.
Get 0% APR financing for 36
months on a 2013 Subaru Forester
and we'll donate 250 dollars to
your choice of 5 charities.
>> MY LITTLE GIRL WAS SO FULL OF
LIFE AND WANTED A HORSE SO BADLY
AND WAS GOING TO GET BOOT GOES
CHRISTMAS AND SHE IS NOT COMING
HOME.
I WANT TO KEEP TALKING ABOUT HER
AND...ALL THE THING SHE LOVED TO
DO.
>> I FOUND A JOURNAL AND I
OPENED THE BOOK AND IT WAS WHAT
I NEEDED BECAUSE IT SAID I LOVE
YOU SO MUCH.
IT IS LIKE SHE KNEW WE WERE
GOING TO NEED SOMETHING TO HELP
US GET THROUGH THIS.
>>Neil: WE CANNOT IMAGINE HOW
SOMETHING LIKE THIS COULD HAPPEN
TO SO MANY INNOCENT LITTLE
CHILDREN.
A LOT OF FOLKS ARE ASKING, HOW
COULD GOD LET IT HAPPEN?
HOW COULD HE LET THE BEAUTIFUL
CHILDREN DIE?
IT IS A NATURAL QUESTION.
THE SENIOR PASTOR OF THE
POTTER'S HOUSE WILL TRY TO GIVE
US ANSWERS.
WHAT DO YOU SAY, BISHOP?
>>Guest: FIRST, WHAT IS DEEPER
THAN THE QUESTION IS A PLACE OF
PAIN IT COMES FROM, WHERE WE
KNELL HAVE A TENDENCY TO WANT TO
FIND A RATIONAL REASON FOR THIS
EVENT AND SOMETIMES WE NEED TO
HOLD SOMEONE RESPONSIBLE BUT GOD
DOES NOT SHOOT GUNS.
WHAT WE ARE ASKING GOD TO DO IS
TAKE AWAY HUMAN WILL.
IN REALITY, THE FREEDOM OF WILL
CAUSES US TO BE CREATIVE AND
LETS US CREATE INVENTIONS AND
CHOOSE TO MAKE DECISIONS ON OUR
OWN AND THAT MAKES US UNIQUE BUT
SOMETIMES WHEN WE HAVE THAT
FREEDOM OF WILL AND IT GOES
AWRY, GOD CREATED FREEDOM OF
WILL AND GAVE US A CONSCIENCE
AND GAVE US VOICES TO GUIDE US
ON THE PROCESS AND 90 PERCENT OF
THE TIME IT WORKED.
IN CASES WHERE THEY COULD BE
EMOTIONAL OR MENTAL DISTURBANCES
THEY GO ASKEW AND IN THOSE
CASES, IT CANND UP IN THIS TYPE
OF TRAGEDY.
>>Neil: YOU KNOW, BISHOP,
PEOPLE HEARING THAT AND IT IS
CONSOLING BUT IT WILL BE LITTLE
RELIEF TO THE PARENTS OF THE
LITTLE BOYS AND GIRLS WHO COULD
SAY YES, WE BELIEVE IN THIS IDEA
OF FREE WILL AND MAN CREATES HIS
OWN LOT BUT YOU WOULD THING NEW
AND THEN GOD WOULD INTERVENE.
>>Guest: I THINK WHAT WE
REALLY NEED TO DO IS TO TAKE OUR
THOUGHTS DOWN TO THE PRACTICAL
THINGS THAT ARE IN OUR REACH AS
HUMANS, TO BE OUR BROTHER'S
KEEPER AND WATCH OUT FOR PEOPLE
WHO ARE DISPLAYING EMERGE
BEHAVIORS, TO BE ABLE TO
IDENTIFY THEM BEFORE THIS SORT
OF THING BEGINS TO HAPPEN, AND,
THEN, I HAVE TO CONDITION OCCUR
WITH THE GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT
WHAT SO ELOQUENTLY SAID DURING
THE FUNERAL THAT FAITH IS A
GIFT, IT REALLY TRULY IS A GIFT
AND TO THOSE PEOPLE WHO DO HAVE
FAITH, OF ANY KIND, THAT IS A
GIFT AND PARTICULARLY FOR ME AS
A CHRISTIAN TO RECOGNIZE FAITH
DOES NOT MEAN THERE IS NO DOUBT,
THAT THERE ARE NO UNRESOLVED
QUESTIONS, FAITH IS MORE
EFFECTIVE WHEN THERE ARE NO
RATIONAL REASONS TO EXPLAIN
ITSELF, IT LIVES ITSELF TO THE
REVEALED PRESENCE OF GOD AND TO
UNDERSTAND THAT AND TO WALK IN
THAT AND TO BELIEVE IT IS SO
IMPORTANT OF THE FAITH CAN EXIST
IN THE PRESENCE OF DOUBT THE WAY
COURAGE CAN EXIST IN THE
PRESENCE OF FEAR.
PEOPLE ARE CONFLICTED.
IT WILL TAKE TIME TO PROCESS.
WE WON'T PROCESS THIS THIS WEEK,
THE FAMILIES WILLING NOT PROCESS
FOR YEARS.
I CAUTIOUS LOOKING FOR QUICK
ANSWERS IT LIFE WHICH IS
COMPLICATED.
>>Neil: FOR THOSE WHO ARE NOT
RELIGIOUS AND SAY, WHY SHOULD I
BE RELIGIOUS IN A WORLD WHERE
EVIL SEEMS TO HAVE WON MORE
OFTEN LATELY WHETHER IT IS A
SHOOTING LIKE THIS OR THE
SHOOTING IN COLORADO OR A COUPLE
OF WEEKS BACK AT A SHOPPING
MALL, INDISCRIMINATE, SEPARATE
CASES ALL, I GRANT YOU, BUT IT
REINFORCES THE VIEW HELD BY SOME
THAT THE WORLD IS A BAD PLACE
AND NO ONE IS LOOKING OVER US.
WHAT DID YOU SAY?
>>Guest: WELL, TO THOSE PEOPLE
WHO FEEL THAT WAY, MY RESPONSE
WOULD BE THE STATS PROVEN YOU
WRONG.
THE TRUTH IS, MILLIONS OF LITTLE
CHILDREN ALL OVER THE WORLD GOT
UP THIS MORNING, WENT ABOUT
THEIR AFFAIRS AND ARRIVED SAFELY
AND THEY DON'T MAKE THE 6:00
NEWS.
IT IS ABOUT -- IT IS NOT THE
PLANS THAT TAKE OFF SHAVELY THAT
REPORTED BUT THOSE THAT CRASH.
IN THE NEWS CYCLE TODAY IT SEEMS
OVERWHELMING BUT THERE ARE
MILLIONS OF PARENTS WHO WILL
TUCK THEIR CHILDREN IN BED AND
SAY THANK YOU LORD, IT WILL NOT
GET THE PRESS OR THE HEADLIGHTS
BUT GOD HAS BEEN GOOD TO
MILLIONS OF PEOPLE AROUND THIS
WORLD IN OBVIOUS WAYS AND FOR
THAT, WE SAY THANK YOU.
>>Neil: DO YOU SHARE THE
NOTION THAT WE HAVE BECOME MORE
DETACHED RELIGIOUSLY AND WE
DON'T PRAY IN OUR SCHOOLS, NOT
AS MAN PRAY, PERIOD, NOT SAYING
THIS BRINGS THIS ON, BUT, IN
THIS DETACHED RELIGIOUS WORLD,
WE ARE FOCUSED ON MORE OF THE
SECULAR WORLDLY THINGS AND WE
DON'T THINK ABOUT GOD, WE DON'T
THING ABOUT HIGHER THINGS UNTIL
WE SEE HORRIBLE THINGS.
I DON'T KNOW IF THAT IS SO GOOD.
>>Guest: WELL, TO HAVE A GOD
CENTERED LIFE IS A GREAT THING
AND VERY IMPORTANT THING TO HAVE
BUT THAT IS ONE CONTRIBUTION
AMONG MANY CONTRIBUTIONS.
THE LEGAL OF CIVILITY IN OUR
COUNTRY AMONG THE MOST
DISTINGUISHED PEOPLE IN OUR
COUNTRY HAS DROPPED TO AN ALL
TIME LOW.
ANYTHING GOES TODAY.
WHILE MOST PEOPLE CAN FIGHT FOR
THEIR OPINION AND KEEP IT IN
GUIDE LINES OF HUMAN RESPECT AND
DIGNITY WE MUST ALWAYS BE
COGNIZANT THAT WE DON'T WANT TO
BE THE MATCH THAT LIGHT AS FIRE
IN SOMEONE'S EMOTION WHOSE
AGREES WITH OUR VIEWS BUT TAKES
IT TO A DISRESPECTFUL LEVEL.
I HAVE BEEN CONCERNED ABOUT THE
WAY OUR COUNTRY IS GOING IN
TERMS OF HOW WE ARE SO DIVIDED
BOTH DIVISIONS EXACERBATED AND
PROMOTED AND PROFITED OFF OF, AT
A TIME WE NEED TO BE UNITED.
I WELCOME DEBATE.
BUT THE DISRESPECT THAT IS
SHOCKING AMONG THE PROFESSIONALS
HAS BECOME REPREHENSIBLE IN
CASES LIKE THIS AND ALL OF IT IS
CONNECTED INCLUDING OUR
DISRESPECT OF GOD, OUR
DISRESPECT OF FAMILY, OUR
DISRESPECT OF EACH OTHER, AND WE
DON'T HAVE TO AGREE ON
EVERYTHING BUT WE DO NOT HAVE TO
BE DISAGREEABLE AS A
CIVILIZATION AS WE HAVE BECOME.
>>Neil: I HAD SOME EXPERTS WHO
SAY WE HAVE TO WATCH AT THE
LEAST WANT OUR MORE DISAGREEABLE
OR ODD CHARACTERS, SCRUTINIZE
THOSE WHOSE BEHAVIOR IS OUTSIDE
THE NORM OR JUST IS DIFFERENT.
HOW WOULD GOD OR HOW DO YOU FEEL
ABOUT THAT?
>>Guest: WELL, WHAT THIS
BRINGS TO MIND IS NOT ONLY WE
NEED TO HAVE REAL CONVERSATIONS
ABOUT MENTAL HEALTH WE ARE
STARTING TO HAVE, I WELCOME THE
CONVERSATIONS THIS WE ARE HAVING
ABOUT GUN CONTROL BUT IF WE HAVE
THAT APART FROM HUMAN BEHAVIORS,
WE WILL NOT GET THERE.
GUNS DON'T SHOOT THEMSELVES.
WE HAVE TO ASK, AM I MY WHERE'S
KEEPER?
IN REALITY, WE ARE, WHETHER HIGH
BROTHER IS UNSTABLE, BIPORE
PARTICULAR OR ANGRY BUT DO NOT
POLARIZE PARTICULAR PEOPLE AND
IDENTIFY THEM, WE MUST ALSO
UNDERSTAND THAT SOMEONE WHO WITH
NO MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES IN THE
PAST CAN SNAP, WORKING AT THE
DESK IN -- NEXT TO YOU.
IT IS INCUMBENT UPON US TO WANT
OUT FOR EACH OTHER LIKE WE ARE
DOING AND THE LOVE WE SENDING TO
CONNECTICUT.
WE NEED TO DO THAT IN TIMES OF
TRAUMA AND HURRICANES BUT TO
LOOK ACROSS FROM DESK TO DESK,
AGAINST TO FENCE, BECOME MORE
BROTHERLY LOVE AND CENTRAL IF
OUR INTERESTS RATHER THAN TO BE
CONSUMED WITH OUR OWN INDIVIDUAL
AGENDAS.
>>Neil: THANK YOU VERY MUCH,
BISHOP.
>>Guest: THANK YOU AND MAY GOD
BLESS EVERY BEREAVED FAMILY.
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
FLAVOR, MEET FOOD.
IT'S TIME
FOR SWANSON FLAVOR BOOST.
CONCENTRATED BROTH
IN EASY TO USE PACKETS.
MIX IT INTO SKILLET DISHES,
FOR AN INSTANT DOSE OF...
HELL-O!
[ Female Announcer ]
GET RECIPES AT FLAVORBOOST.COM.
>>Neil: INVESTIGATORS ARE
TRYING TO PUT TOGETHER WHAT
CAUSED ADAM LANZA TO STOP AND
ARE HOPING TO FIND ANSWERS FROM
HIS OWN TOWN.
WHAT DO YOU HEAR, MOLLY?
>>Reporter: A NUMBER OF
REPORTS HAVE COME OUT.
NANCY ATLANTA'S -- LANZA'S
FRIEND HAVE GIVEN INSIGHT.
A REPORT IS ABOUT A MEDIATOR
THAT HELPED HER AND HER HUSBAND
WITH THE 2009 DIVORCE.
ACCORDING TO THIS REPORT, NANCY
LANZA WAS CONCERNED ABOUT
LEAVING HER SON ALONE.
THE PARENTS PUT A LOT OF TIME
INTO THE SON, ACCOMMODATING HIM
AND HIS SPECIAL NEEDS AND THAT
IS THE TYPE OF PICTURE HER
FRIENDS PAINTED TODAY.
SHE WAS A DEVOTED MOTHER THAT
CARED A LOT ABOUT HER SON.
AS IF THE IDEA SHE WAS A
ENTHUSIAST, THEY SAY THAT IS
TRUE SHE HAD AN INTEREST BUT IT
WAS PART OF A HOBBY.
LISTEN TO ONE OF HER FRIENDS.
>> THIS IS NO FROM MY VIEWPOINT,
NO INSIGHT INTO, NO INDICATIONS
THAT IS WHAT HAPPENED, EVER.
SHE TALKED ABOUT ADAM AND IT WAS
VERY LOVING, AND SHE WAS A
DEVOTED MOTHER.
>>Reporter: THEIR POINT WAS
SHE WAS A DEVOTED MOTHER THAT
CARED ABOUT HER SON THAT HAD
SOME TROUBLE, CLEARLY, BUT NO
ONE SAW THIS COMING AND THEY DID
NOT BELIEVE SHE SAW THIS COMING
AND SHE NEVER LED THEM TO
BELIEVE HE WAS VIOLENT.
>>Neil: NOT MUCH TALK ABOUT
WHAT THE FATHER DID OR DIDN'T DO
OR SAY OR DIDN'T SAY.
>>Reporter: A LOT OF THE
FRIENDS MUCH NANCY SAY SHE DID
NOT TALK ABOUT HER EX-HUSBAND
BUT INTERESTING INSIGHT FROM TWO
FRIENDS WAS SHE WAS SO DEVOTED
TO HER SON SHE WORKED ON GETTING
HIM INTO COLLEGE AND WOULD BE
WILLING TO MOVE FROM THIS
COMMUNITY AND TO GO TO WHEREVER
IT WAS HE FOUND A PLACE TO BE
EDUCATED.
>>Neil: AMAZING.
NOW SHE IS DEAD WITH SO MANY
OTHERS.
MOLLY LINE, IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
ON SUCH A CRAZY DAY AND A FEW
DAYS, WHEN MONEY STOPS TALKING,
YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENED IN THIS
SMALL TOWN IS LEAVING SILENCE
THAT EVEN NOW IS DEAFENING.
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>>Neil: TRADING ON FRIDAY WAS
VERY LIGHT AND IN THIS
SUPPOSEDLY CAPITALIST COUNTRY,
HEARTS WERE HEAVY AND FOR A
BRIEF MOMENT, TODAY, IT WAS
SILENT.
A MOMENT SILENCE SPEAKS VOLUMES
WHEN NO ONE IS SPEAKING AT ALL.
WHEN THEY ARE JUST WATCHING.
AND THINKING.
AND WONDERING.
AND IN A PLACE LIKE WALL STREET
WHERE MONEY MEANS EVERYTHING,
FOR A BRIEF MOMENT, IT MEANT
NOTHING.
MONEY POWERLESS TO BRING BACK 20
LIVES, MONEY USELESS TO MAKE SO
MANY DEVASTATED PARENTS WHOLE.
MONEY THAT COULD NOT BUY ONE OF
THEM A HAPPY CHRISTMAS NOW.
OR EVEN BRING IF A BETTER NEW
YEAR.
THERE ARE MANY THINGS MONEY
CANNOT BUY INCLUDING PEACE OF
MIND.
THE REALIZATION OF THAT IS THE
MORE HUMBLING REALITIES OF ALL
OF THIS.
THAT THE THINGS WE SCRAMBLE FOR
IN LIFE AND FIGHT FOR IN LIFE
AND SCRATCH AND CLAW EACH OTHER
TO GAIN AN EDGE IN LIFE IS SO
SILLY WHEN WE ARE DEAD AND GONE.
AND WE THING MORE OF THE
FRAGILITY OF LIFE AND LESS OF
OUR "STUFF" IN LIFE AND WE TAKE
A LOOK AT THE LITTLE CHILDREN
JUST STARTING LIFE AND WE THINK
ABOUT THIS STUFF EVEN LESS.
"STUFF" DOESN'T MATTER.
NONE OF THIS IS TO SAY IN THE
GREAT CAPITALIST SOCIETY WE
DON'T