THROUGH FORGIVENESS.
>> WE WANT EVERYONE TO KNOW
THAT OUR HEARTS AND OUR
PRAYERS GO OUT TO THEM.
THIS INCLUDES THE FAMILY OF
THE SHOOTER.
>> MORE ON HOW HIS FAMILY A
FINDING STRENGTH THROUGH LOVE
AHEAD.
>> PLUS, ON THIS SUNDAY
MORNING, AS MANY OF YOU HEAD
TO CHURCH RIGHT NOW, WE TAKE A
LOOK AT OUR CULTURE, HOW IT
HAS CHANGED AND HOW WE GIVE
BACK TO SOCIETY AND FAITH
INSTEAD OF FEAR.
"FOX & FRIENDS" STARTS RIGHT
NOW.
GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE,
THANKS SO MUCH FOR JOINING US
BRIGHT AND EARLY GREAT TO BE
BACK WITH DAVE BRIGGS, I'VE
MISSED YOU FOR THE PAST COUPLE
OF WEEKENDS.
>> YOU, TOO.
>> Alisyn: AND WONDERFUL TO
HAVE YOU IN, KELLY, IN FOR
CLAYTON.
>> IT'S GOOD TO BE BACK IN
THIS CHAIR.
>> Julie:  YOU AND I BOTH HAVE
KIDS THE SAME AGE, 30, 40
MINUTES AWAY FROM NEWTOWN IN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN A TOWN
VERY SIMILAR.
THIS HIT VERY CLOSE TO HOME
FOR US AND FOR A LOT OF
PEOPLE.
>> YOU KNOW, BASED ON THAT
POINT, IF IT CAN HAPPEN IN
NEWTOWN AND IT CAN HAPPEN
ANYWHERE, IN A SMALL RURAL
COMMUNITY AND HAGGERSTOWN,
MARYLAND, AN IDYLLIC
COMMUNITY, TOWN OF 30,000,
JUST LIKES NEWTOWN, AND PEOPLE
ARE MOURNING AND WEEPING AS
THEY MOURN FOR THE TEACHERS AT
SANRY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> JUST WHEN YOU THINK YOU CAN
BE COMPOSED AND KEEP IT
TOGETHER AND MAYBE THE TEARS
WILL HAVE STOPPED, THEY PUT
OUT THE NAMES AND AGES OF THE
VICTIMS AND EVEN NOT KNOWING
THEM, BUT JUST TO READ THROUGH
THEIR NAMES AND THEIR AGES IS
JUST WRETCHING.
WE WILL SHOW YOU SOME OF THEIR
NAMES NOW, THE VICTIMS, THERE
WERE 12.
WE'LL SHOW THEM LATER TO YOU,
BASICALLY 20 CHILDREN AND
YOUNGER THAN WE THOUGHT,
REMEMBER THAT PRESIDENT OBAMA
AND HIS FIRST REPORT THAT THEY
WERE BETWEEN FIVE AND TEN
YEARS OLD.
THEY WERE REALLY JUST SIX AND
SEVEN YEARS OLD, ALL OF THEM
AND IT'S ALSO TO KNOW, WE
DIDN'T KNOW AT THE TIME, WHAT
CLOSE RANGE THEY WERE KILLED.
HOW GOOD OF A MARKSMAN THIS
SHOOTER WAS AND WE NOW KNOW
TRAGICALLY THEY WERE SHOT MANY
TIM
TIMES.
>> THE MOTHER OF THE SHOOTER,
NANCY, WAS A GUN COLLECTOR AND
TAUGHT HER SON HOW TO SHOOT
AND WE'LL BE ASKING QUESTIONS
ABOUT THIS IN THE DAYS AHEAD
AND ALL USED IN THE MASSACRE
WERE TIED, REGISTERED TO HER,
AND THE SHOOTER DID TRY TO BUY
HIS OWN RIFLE DAYS BEFORE THE
SHOOTING.
HE WAS DENIED.
THE SCHOOLING OF THE SHOOTER
ALSO NOW WE'RE LEARNING ABOUT,
KELLY AND HE WAS APPARENTLY
SCHOOLED THROUGH THE SYSTEM
AND SOMEWHERE WITH PULLED OUT.
AND IT IT LOOKS LIKE SOMEWHERE
AROUND--
>> WE STILL DON'T KNOW WHY HE
WAS PULLED OUT OF SCHOOL AND
THAT'S UNDER INVESTIGATION AND
APPARENTLY HIS MOTHER THOUGHT
IT WAS BEST HE WAS HOME
SCHOOLED FOR A TIME AND IN
HIGH SCHOOL MANY DESCRIBED HIM
AS BEING VERY SMART,
BRILLIANT, BUT VERY MUCH TO
HIMSELF AND EVEN REPORTS THAT
HE ALWAYS CARRIED AROUND A
BRIEFCASE OR SOMETHING J.
>> YEAH, A BLACK BRIEFCASE.
>> STRANGE BEHAVIOR AND PEOPLE
WILL CONTINUE TO INVESTIGATE
THAT.
>> PEOPLE SAY THEY HAVE A
GREAT AMOUNT OF EVIDENCE AND
PERHAPS THAT WILL LEAD TO SOME
CALL FOR THIS, THE BIG
QUESTION THAT WE HAVE IS WHY
AND THAT'S A QUESTION THAT
STILL REMAINS TO BE ANSWERED.
POLICE ARE HOPING THAT AS THEY
PIECE TOGETHER THE
INVESTIGATION--
>> PERHAPS BECAUSE THERE'S NO
CONNECTION BETWEEN THE SHOOTER
AND THE SCHOOL.
>> NEVER ATTENDED THE SCHOOL.
>> Alisyn: I THOUGHT THERE
WERE SOME REPORTS AS A CHILD
HE DID.
>> HE DID NOT ATTEND SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY.
>> Alisyn: VERY INTERESTING.
>> AND THE MOM DID NOT WORK
THERE.
>> Alisyn: AND THERE WERE
CONFUSING REPORTS, A TEACHER,
SUBSTITUTE TEACHER AND I READ
A REPORT SHE WAS A TEACHERS
AIDE.
THERE WERE SOME REPORTS HE HAD
AN ALTERCATION EARLIER IN THE
WEEK.
>> WITH THE SCHOOL.
>> Alisyn: WITH OFFICIALS AT
THE SCHOOL.
>> I SPOKE WITH LIEUTENANT
PAUL VANCE WITH THE STATE
POLICE YESTERDAY AFTERNOON AND
ASKED HIM WAS THERE A PRIOR
ALTERCATION A COUPLE OF DAYS
PRIOR TO THIS INCIDENT BEING
CARRIED OUT AND HE WENT ON TO
SAY, WE HAVE NO CONFIRMATION
OF THAT.
HE DENIED THAT IT WAS
HAPPENING, BUT APPARENTLY
THEY'RE STILL INVESTIGATING
ALL ASPECTS OF THIS, BUT IT
WAS REPORTED PREVIOUSLY THAT
PERHAPS IT WAS AN ALTERCATION,
AGAIN, AND LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE, NEW YORKING THAT DOWN.
AS WE LEARN MORE ABOUT THE
VICTIMS OF THIS TRAGEDY IN
MIDTOWN COMMUNITY IS COMING
TOGETHER TO SUPPORT EACH OTHER
AS WELL.
♪
EMOTIONAL VIGILS CONTINUED
TONIGHT AND TODAY.
AND PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL
TRAVEL TO NEWTOWN TO MEET WITH
THE VICTIM'S FAMILIES AND
PETER, WHAT CAN YOU TELL US.
>> KELLY, I CAN TELL YOU THAT
AROUND HERE, IT'S STILL, IT'S
VERY HARD FOR FOLKS TO DEAL
WITH ESPECIALLY SINCE
YESTERDAY WE FOUND OUT THAT 16
OF THE 26 VICTIMS INSIDE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WERE
BORN IN 2006, ANOTHER FOUR
BORN IN 2005 AND THERE HAVE
BEEN MEMORIALS POPPING UP.
AND THE PARK WE'RE SANG THERE.
A GROUP OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL STUDENTS IN
THE SCHOOL WHEN IT WAS
EVACUATED, IN THE FIREHOUSE,
THEY WERE HOLDING A YARD SALE
SELLING THEIR TOYS AND THEIR
THINGS, TRYING TO RAISE MONEY
FOR THE AFFECTED FAMILIES,
REALLY FOR THEIR CLASSMATES.
THERE HAVE BEEN MANY MORE
FOLKS IN THIS AREA, LIT
CANDLES AND HUNG POSTERS OR
BALLOONS AND MANY, MANY MORE
HAVE ATTENDED VIGILS AND A
VERY TOUCHING ONE LAST NIGHT
FOR THE 27-YEAR-OLD TEACHER
WHO DIED TRYING TO SAVE SOME
OF HER STUDENTS, VICTORIA
SOTO.
>> THE PAIN, HOW THOSE MOTHERS
MUST BE BE FEELING AT THIS
TIME.
MY ONLY CHILD, BUT I COULDN'T
PICTURE THAT AND THAT'S WHY
I'M HERE TODAY.
BECAUSE SHE SAVED SO MANY
KIDS' LIVES.
>> Reporter:  I SPOKE WITH THE
PARENTS OF A STUDENT WHO SAW
MRS. SOTO GET SHOT AND THEY
STILL HAVEN'T TOLD THEIR SON
ABOUT HER ULTIMATE FATE
BECAUSE THEY THINK THAT AFTER
EVERYTHING THAT'S HAPPENED
THIS WEEK AND EVERYTHING ELSE
THAT HE HAS SEEN, INCLUDING
SOME OF HIS CLASSMATES BEING
SHOT, THAT THEY THINK IT'S TOO
MUCH TO HANDLE AT THIS TIME.
AND PRESIDENT OBAMA IS GOING
TO BE HERE THIS EVENING FOR AN
INTERFAITH VIGIL AT NEWTOWN
HIGH SCHOOL AND HE'S GOING TO
TRY TO HELP HEAL THE COMMUNITY
WHO SEEMS TO FEEL WORSE WITH
EVERY NEW PIECE OF INFORMATION
THAT COMES OUT.
>> THEY WERE FIRST GRADERS,
THEY WERE DOING KIDS STUFF.
IT'S THE KIND OF STUFF YOU'D
SEND YOUR KIDS OR YOUR
GRANDKIDS OUT THE DOOR OUT TO
FIRST GRADE.
>> AND AGAIN, COUNSELING WILL
BE AVAILABLE AT A NEARBY
INTERMEDIATE SCHOOL IN THE
GYM.
WE'RE TOLD THAT THERE ARE
GRIEF COUNSELORS FROM ACROSS
NEW ENGLAND AND THERAPY DOGS
AND THERE'S FOOD, A MEMORIAL
BUILDINGEN LAST NIGHT BEFORE
THEY WRAPPED THINGS UP FOR THE
DAY, THERE WERE ABOUT A
HUNDRED CARS IN THE PARKING
LOT.
BACK TO YOU IN NEW YORK.
>> Alisyn: PETER, THANKS SO
MUCH.
GIVEN ALL THE CRUSHING PAIN
FOR THAT COMMUNITY AND
EVERYONE, IT'S ALWAYS
ASTOUNDING WHEN A VICTIM'S
FAMILY MEMBER HUNG OUT AND
SPEAKS WITH AN OPEN HEART AND
SPEAKS WITH GENEROSITY ABOUT
THE SHOOTER AND THE SHOOTER'S
FAMILY AND THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT
ROBERT PARKER DID.
HIS DAUGHTER WAS ONE OF THE
YOUNGEST VICTIMS AND HER NAME
WAS EMILIE PARKER, JUST SIX
YEARS OLD AND HE FOUND HIS WAY
THROUGH THE CROWD TO THE
MICROPHONE YESTERDAY AND HERE
IS WHAT HE HAD TO SAY.
>> FIRST OF ALL, I'D REALLY
LIKE TO OFFER OUR DEEPEST
CONDOLENCES TO ALL THE
FAMILIES WHO ARE DIRECTLY
AFFECTED BY THIS SHOOTING.
IT'S A HORRIFIC TRAGEDY AND WE
WANT EVERYBODY TO KNOW THAT
OUR HEARTS AND OUR PRAYERS GO
OUT TO THEM.
THIS INCLUDES THE FAMILY OF
THE SHOOTER.
I CAN'T IMAGINE HOW HARD THIS
EXPERIENCE MUST BE BE FOR YOU.
AND I WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT
OUR FAMILY AND OUR SUPPORT YOU
AS WELL.
MY DAUGHTER EMILY WOULD BE ONE
OF THE FIRST ONES THAT BE
STANDING AND GIVING HER LOVE
AND SUPPORT TO ALL THOSE
VICTIMS BECAUSE THAT'S THE
TYPE OF PERSON THAT SHE IS.
NOT BECAUSE OF ANY PARENTING
THAT MY WIFE AND I COULD HAVE
DONE, BUT BECAUSE THOSE ARE
THE GIFTS THAT WERE GIVEN TO
HER BY HER HEAVENLY FATHER.
>> THAT'S AN AMAZING STATEMENT
FROM ROBBIE PARKER.
YOU CAN SEE THAT HE'S
DEFINITELY TORN WITH THE LOSS
OF HIS DAUGHTER.
THE OLDEST DAUGHTER AND HE
WENT ON TO EXPLAIN WHAT KIND
OF PERSON EMILY IS, SHE WAS AN
ARTIST AND SHE CARRIED AROUND
MARKERS AND IN FACT, SHE JUST
RECENTLY LOST HER GRANDFATHER
AND SHE WOULD DRAW CARDS, SHE
WAS A BUDDING ARTIST AND SHE
WOULD DRAW CARDS FOR PEOPLE
WHO WERE IN PAIN OR AGONY TO
TRY TO EASE THEIR BURDEN AND
WHEN HER GRANDFATHER LYING IN
THE CASKET.
SHE DREW A CARD AND PUTS IT IN
THE CASKET WITH A MESSAGE OF
ENCOURAGEMENT TO HER GRANDPA.
AND YOU SEE ROBBIE'S
WILLINGNESS TO FORGIVE, SO
POWERFUL AND SO POIGNANT FOR
THE TIMES IN WHICH WE LIVE
RIGHT NOW WHERE WE DO NEED
THAT, THAT PRECIOUS BALM OF
FORGIVENESS AND I REMEMBER
TALKING ABOUT THE SAME THING,
BUT IT'S SO HARD, BUT WHEN YOU
BRING A COMMUNITY TOGETHER
LIKE THIS, GUYS BEING IN
CONNECTICUT NOW HOW CLOSE KNIT
THIS IS.
AND IS AN AIR ESPECIALLY NEW
TOURN, YOU EXPECT THIS TO
HAPPEN.
>> IT'S A SMALL STATE.
IT'S HARD TO SAY THAT I'D BE
THIS FOR GIVING AND ROBBIE,
YOU HOPE NEVER HAVING TO TALK
ABOUT HIS LAST WORDS TO HIS
SIX-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER.
>> SHE WOKE UP BEFORE I LEFT
AND I'D ACTUALLY BEEN TEACHING
HER POUR GEESE BEFORE I LEFT
THE LAST CONVERSATION WAS IN
PORTUGESE AND SHE TOLD ME GOOD
MORNING, AND ASKED HOW I WAS
DOING I SAID I WAS DOING WELL.
SHE SAID THAT SHE LOVED ME AND
I GAVE HER A KISS AND I WAS
OUT THE DOOR.
>> Alisyn: THERE OBVIOUSLY ARE
19 OTHER VICTIMS, ONE OF THEM
IS GRACE McDONALD, SHE WAS, I
THINK, SEVEN YEARS OLD,
POSSIBLY SIX ALL THE VICTIMS
WERE, AND EVERYBODY TALKED HOW
SHE LOOKED LIKE A LITTLE ANGEL
AND A DOLL.
PIERCING DEEP, DEEP BLUE EYES
AND BEAUTIFUL BLOND HAIR AND
HER FAMILY WANT TODAY PUT OUT
A STATEMENT SAYING WE'RE
OVERWHELMED BY THE OUTPOURING
OF LOVE AND SUPPORT FROM SO
MANY PEOPLE.
OUR DAUGHTER GRACE WAS THE
LIGHT AND LOVE OF OUR FAMILY
AND WORDS CANNOT EXPRESS OUR
LOSS.
CHRIS AND JACK, I BELIEVE
THEIR 0 OTHER SON, MCDONALD.
>> WERE THERE WASHING SIGNS
THAT ADAM LANZA WAS PLANNING
SUCH A CRIME.
A FBI PROFILER WILL JOIN US
LIVE.
♪
[ roasting firewood ]
MANY HOT DOGS
ARE WITHIN YOU.
TRY PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO,
IT'S THE POWER OF PEPTO,
BUT IT FITS IN YOUR POCKET.
NOW TELL THE WORLD
DANIEL...
OF PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO.
NOW TELL THE WORLD
DANIEL...
It's hard to see opportunity
in today's challenging
environment.
Unless you have the right
perspective.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
has the vision
and experience to look beyond
the obvious.
We'll uncover opportunities,
find hidden risk,
and make success a reality.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>>  WELCOME BACK TO "FOX &
FRIENDS" THIS MORNING.
WE'RE LEARNING NOW INFORMATION
ABOUT THE GUNMAN WHO CARRIED
OUT THE HORRIFIC CRIME.
WHAT WERE THE WARNING SIGNS IF
ANY AND IS IT POSSIBLE TO
FORSEE SOMEONE ON THE BRINK OF
CREATING SUCH A CRIME.
LET'S ASK A PROFILER, MARY,
THANKS FOR BEING WITH US.
>> YOU'RE WELCOME.
>> Alisyn: ADAM LANZA WAS
DESCRIBED AS BEING PECULIAR, A
LONER, A TECHNO GEEK OR A
COMPUTER GEEK, BUT NONE OF
THOSE THINGS ARE WARNING
SIGNS.
YOU SAY THAT PEOPLE DON'T
INSTANTLY SNAP.
SO, WHAT SHOULD PEOPLE BE ON
THE LOOKOUT WHEN THEY THINK AT
THAT SOMEONE IS A LITTLE
STRANGE?
>> YOU'RE RIGHT, OUR
EXPERIENCE AND OUR RESEARCH IN
THE FBI IS THAT PEOPLE DON'T
JUST SNAP, THEY DON'T WAKE UP
ONE MORNING AND DECIDE TO
CARRY THIS OUT.
THIS IS A CRIME THAT INVOLVING
PLANNING AP THE PLANNING
INCLUDES GETTING THE GUNS AND
PRACTICING WITH THE GUNS AND
GETTING THE AMMUNITION, AND
SOMETIMES DRESSING UP IN THE
GARB OR THE OUTFIT THAT THEY
INTEND TO WEAR.
ALL OF THAT IS WARNING
BEHAVIOR.
THERE'S ALSO LEAKAGE, WHICH IS
TELLING SOMEONE AHEAD OF TIME
DIRECTLY OR INDIRECTLY, AND IT
MAY BE EVEN IN THE FORM OF
BRAGGING OR SOUNDING LIKE CAN
YOU BELIEVE I'M REALLY GOING
TO DO THIS.
OTHER BEHAVIORS OBSESSED WITH
GUNS OR PRIOR SHOOTERS LIKE
THE COLUMBINE OR THE AURORA
SHOOTER AND AS IT GETS CLOSER
TO THE EVENTS.
IT WOULD BECOME, THEY WOULD
BECOME INVOLVED WITH JUST
REALLY FOCUSING ON THEIR
PLANNING AND HOW THEY'RE GOING
TO CARRY IT OUT.
NOW, SOMEONE CLEAR ACROSS
TOWN, ARE THEY GOING TO BE
AWARE OF THESE WARNING
BEHAVIORS?
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
BUT IS IT SOMEONE THAT'S GOING
TO BE CLOSE TO THE SHOOTSER
THAT WILL BECOME AWARE THAT
THESE BEHAVIORS ARE STARTING
TO MANIFEST AND BUBBLE TO THE
TOP?
THOSE ARE THE PEOPLE WE WANT
TO COME FORWARD AND SAY, I'M
CONCERNED ABOUT THIS, THIS IS
REALLY MORE ATYPICAL.
THIS PERSON IS BECOMING, IS
MAKING THREATS AND THE WARNING
BEHAVIORS ARE BEGINNING TO
SURFACE.
WE HAD A CASE VERY RECENTLY
WHERE THE RATHER CAME FORWARD
TO LAW ENFORCEMENT AND WAS
CONCERNED ABOUT HER SON
BECAUSE HE HAD THREATENED TO
GO INTO A MOVIE THEATER AND
CARRY OUT A SHOOTING SIMILAR
TO AURORA, COLORADO SO WE KNOW
THAT THESE WARNING BEHAVIORS
WORK WHEN YOU IDENTIFY THEM
AND YOU DON'T IGNORE THEM.
>> Dave: AND I REMEMBER ALL
THE WAY BACK TO THE COLUMBINE,
I WAS THERE EVERY DAY AS A
STUDENT JOURNALIST AND SOME
MIGHT BE TOO CLOSE TO NOTICE
THOSE THINGS.
IF SOMEONE, A FAMILY MEMBER OR
A FRIEND RECOGNIZES THIS WHO
DO THEY REPORT IT TO?
THEY DON'T CALL THE FBI, WHO
WANTS TO HEAR THESE THINGS AND
WHO CAN ACT ON THEM?
>> SURE, THEY'RE NOT GOING TO
PICK UP THE PHONE AND CALL THE
FBI, WE UNDERSTAND NA, BUT
THEY CAN CALL A TEACHER, THEY
CAN CALL A RESOURCE OFFICER IN
SCHOOL, THEY CAN CONTACT AN
ADULT NEIGHBOR.
THE PARENTS OF A FRIEND OF
THEIRS, THEY CAN CALL SOMEONE
THAT THEY FEEL WILL GO AND
TAKE THAT INFORMATION TO LAW
ENFORCEMENT, TO SOMEONE WHO IS
ABLE TO FOLLOW THROUGH AND
EVALUATE THAT BEHAVIOR AND IN
EVERY SCHOOL NOW, FOR EXAMPLE,
HAS BEHAVIORAL INTERVENTION
TEAMS OR BEHAVIORAL ASSESSMENT
TEAMS AND ON THOSE TEAMS ARE
LAW ENFORCEMENT PSYCHOLOGIST
AND TEACHERS AND THEY'RE
TRAINED TO LOOK AT THAT KIND
OF BEHAVIOR.
THE IMPORTANT POINT IS, FOR
PEOPLE NOT TO VET IT
THEMSELVES AND SAY, OH,
THEY'RE JUST KIDDING.
THEY DON'T REALLY, THEY'RE NOT
REALLY SERIOUS ABOUT THAT,
PLEASE DON'T DO THAT.
BRING IT TO PEOPLE THAT DO
HAVE THE BACKGROUND, TRAINING
AND EXPERIENCE THAT CAN LOOK
AT IT AND VET IT.
>> Alisyn: SURE.
>> SEE IF THERE'S SOMETHING
THERE.
>> Alisyn: ALERT THE EXPERT.
THESE ARE GREAT TIPS AND FOR
PEOPLE TO BE ON THE LOOKOUT
FOR, YOU ALSO SAY IF THEY
START TALKING WITH SUICIDAL
OVERTOWNS, NOT JUST BECOMING
MORE OBSESSIVE, NOT JUST
PERHAPS PLAYING WORD GAMES OR
DRESSING UP, BUT ULTIMATELY,
THEY'RE BEING
SELF-DESTRUCTIVE.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
IF THEY'RE TALKING -- AND
MAYBE IN THE PAST, THEY'VE
SPOKE IN TERMS OF SUICIDE AS A
WAY OUT, BUT THAT BEHAVIOR
NOW, IN CONJUNCTION WITH THE
OTHER ONES I'VE JUST
IDENTIFIED, NOW THAT BEHAVIOR
IN TERMS OF SUICIDE AAL IDEATIO.
THERE'S NOTHING LEFT ANYWAY,
IT'S OVER.
THOSE COMMENTS IN COMBINATION
WITH EVERYTHING ELSE REALLY
TOGETHER IT'S A CUMULATIVE
BEHAVIOR THAT'S IMPORTANT.
>> Dave: HOPEFULLY THE NEXT
ONE OF THESE CAN BE PREVENTED.
MARY ELLEN O'TOOLE, FBI
PROFILER, THANK YOU FOR BEING
WITH US.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Alisyn: SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY HAD NEW SECURITY
MEASURES IN PLACE, BUT THE
SHOOTER SMASHED HIS WAY
THROUGH THE WINDOW.
IS THERE ANY WAY TO MAKE SURE
THAT OUR SCHOOLS ARE SAFER?
THAT'S NEXT.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
IT STARTED LONG AGO.
THE JOY OF GIVING SOMETHING
EVERYTHING YOU'VE GOT.
IT TAKES PASSION.
AND IT'S NOT LETTING UP
ANYTIME SOON.
AT UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company,
WE UNDERSTAND THAT COMMITMENT.
AND ALWAYS HAVE.
SO DOES AARP,
AN ORGANIZATION
SERVING THE NEEDS
OF AMERICANS 50 AND OVER
FOR GENERATIONS.
SO IT'S NO SURPRISE
MILLIONS HAVE CHOSEN
AN AARP Medicare Supplement
Insurance Plan,
INSURED BY UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company.
LIKE ALL STANDARDIZED
MEDICARE SUPPLEMENT PLANS,
THEY HELP COVER
SOME OF THE EXPENSES
MEDICARE DOESN'T PAY.
AND SAVE YOU UP TO THOUSANDS
IN OUT-OF-POCKET COSTS.
TO FIND OUT MORE,
REQUEST YOUR
FREE DECISION GUIDE.
CALL OR GO ONLINE TODAY.
AFTER ALL,
WHEN YOU'RE GOING THE DISTANCE,
IT'S NICE TO HAVE
THE EXPERIENCE AND COMMITMENT
TO GO ALONG WITH YOU.
KEEP DREAMING. KEEP DOING.
GO LONG.
>>  WELCOME BACK EVERYONE.
THANKS SO MUCH FOR JOINING US
EARLY TODAY.
IT'S GREAT TO HAVE KELLY WITH
US.
OBVIOUSLY, AT THIS POINT
SCHOOL SHOOTING AND VIOLENCE
HAVE REACHED EPIDEMIC
PROPORTIONS.
AND WE HAVE TO FIGURE OUT WHAT
TO DO, ENOUGH TALKING AND
OBVIOUSLY THE GRIEF IS SO
STRONG WE NEED TO FIGURE OUT
AND WHAT'S INTERESTING, IT
HAPPENS MORE IN THE UNITED
STATES THAN ANYWHERE ELSE.
WE'RE DOING SOMETHING WRONG.
>> Dave: YEAH, OF COURSE THERE
WAS A TIME WHEN THESE THINGS
WERE NOT HEARD OF, UNCOMMON.
NOW THEY'RE COMMON AND GOING
BACK TO COLUMBINE THAT'S
UNFORTUNATELY WHERE IT STARTED
AND GERALDO RIVERA TAKES A
LOOK BACK AT HOW THIS
UNFORTUNATE AND AS UNFORTUNATE
HAS BECOME A TREND.
>> IT WAS REALLY KIND OF
MAYHEM IN THE ROOM, TRYING TO
FIND YOUR KIDS AND MAKING SURE
THEY'RE SAFE AND THE SITUATION
AND MAKING SURE EVERYBODY ELSE
IS SAFE.
>> FRIDAY'S MASSACRE IN
CONNECTICUT IS AMONG THE THE
WORST SCHOOL SHOOTINGS.
>> IT DOES NOT SEEM REAL, LIKE
IT'S EVEN POSSIBLE.
YOU READ IT IN THE PAPER AND
SEE IT IN THE NEWS, OH, MY
GOTHED, THAT POOR FAMILY AND
THEN YOU HAVE SOMETHING HAPPEN
SO CLOSE TO HOME, I THINK I'M
STILL IN SHOCK, TO BE HONEST
WITH YOU.
>> THE LATEST IN A DREADFUL
SERIES OF MASS MURDERS,
BEGINNING WITH COLUMBINE, HIGH
SCHOOL IN LITTLETON, COLORADO
IN APRIL OF 1999.
12 STUDENTS AND A TEACHER ALL
MURDERED AND 24 INJURED BY
CLASSMATES HARRIS AND KLEBOLD.
>> AND WHERE WE ARE, WE'RE IN
THE BURBS FOR GOD'S SAKE.
THIS WASN'T THE PLACE.
>> AND THE COLUMBINE SLAUGHTER
BEGINS AT # 1:19 AND YELLING
GO, GO.
>> AT FIRST I DIDN'T KNOW IT
WAS REAL.
>> ARMED WITH PIPE BOMBS AND
AUTOMATICS AND THE PAIR
TARGETING ANYONE AND EVERYONE,
AND AFTER MINUTES ENDS IN THE
LIBRARY.
AND A 19-YEAR-OLD EXPELLED
FROM HIS SCHOOL IN GERMANY
OPENS FIRE KILLING 13
TEACHERS, TWO FORMER
CLASSMATES AND A POLICEMAN.
AND DONNING A BLACK NINJA
STYLE OUTFIT WHICH HAS BECOME
THE UNIFORM OF CHOICE FOR
THESE LUNATICS, TARGETS
TEACHERS REPORTEDLY AS REVENGE
FOR HIS REVENT EXPULSION.
FIVE YEARS LATER BACK ON OUR
SHORES THE CAMPUS OF VIRGINIA
TECH THE SCENE OF THE WORST
EVER SLAUGHTER OF A SCHOOL
GUNMAN ON A U.S. CAMPUS.
>> HE OPENED THE DOOR AND
STARTED SHOOTING THE PROFESSOR
AND THE CLASSMATES.
>> AND HE KILLS 32 AND WOUNDS
15 OTHERS IN TWO SEPARATE
ATTACKS.
>> AT THAT TIME WE HEARD THE
GUNSHOTS AND WE COULD HEAR
SCREAMS AND IT WAS, IT WAS
HORRIBLE AND THEN WE SAW, AS
POLICE JUST STORMED THE
BUILDING AND I WAS CALLING MY
FRIEND TO TELL THEM LIKE,
WHEREVER THEY WERE TO STAY
PUT.
>> TWO YEARS PRIOR, CHO HAD
BEEN ACCUSED OF STALKING TWO
FEMALE STUDENTS AT WHICH TIME
HE WAS ORDERED TO ATTEND ANGER
MANAGEME
MANAGEMENT, DIAGNOSED WITH
SEVERE ANXIETY DISORDERS.
>> BASED ON THAT CONTACT WITH
THE ANXIETY--
>> LAW PREVENTS VIRGINIA TECH
FROM UNDERSTANDING THE
SEVERITY.
>> AS I UNDERSTAND IT, EVEN
THE THE PARENTS CANNOT REVEAL
OR HAVE THAT INFORMATION
SHARED.
>> IN FINLANDS SEVEN MONTHS
LATER, ANOTHER SCHOOL SHOOTING
RESULTING IN EIGHT FATALITIES.
>> IT'S VERY SAD FACT THESE
HAPPEN.
>> THE PERPETRATOR, A
18-YEAR-OLD STUDENT WHO POLICE
SAY WAS FREQUENTLY BULLIED,
BUT WHO OFFICIALS DESCRIBE AS
A MILITANT RADICAL.
>> THE PRELIMINARY ANALYSIS WE
HAVE, HE'S QUITE A LONELY
PERSON.
AND HE HAS A GREAT ANGER
AGAINST SOCIETY AND HE
EXPRESSED EXTREME RADICAL
THOUGHTS.
>> AND HE POSTS A PHOTO OF
HIMSELF ON YOUTUBE HOLDING A
GUN IN ONE HAND AND WEARING A
T-SHIRT THAT READS "HUMANITY
IS OVERRATED" WHICH BRINGS US
BACK TO NEWTON.
>> WE WERE JUST IN THE MIDDLE
OF GYM WHEN WE HEARD SOME
GUNSHOTS AND THEN THE POWER
WENT OUT AND THE GYM TEACHER
DIRECTED US TO STAY AGAINST
THE WALL AND EVERYBODY STARTS
KIND OF PANICKING.
WE HEAR A LOT MORE GUNSHOTS
AND THE AMBULANCE GAME, BUT
THEN THE POLICE HAD HUSBAND
R--
HAD US RUN OUT OF THE BUILDING
TO THE FIRE DEPARTMENT.
>> Kelly: AND THANK GERALDO
FOR THAT REPORT, SHOWING THE
M
MAGNITUDE OF HOW WIDESPREAD
THIS IS.
AND THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES EVEN SAYING ON
FRIDAY THERE'S TOO MUCH OF
THIS GOING ON AND THE
PRESIDENT GIVING A LIST OF
PLACES WHERE IT'S AFFECTED US
MOST DEEPLY.
>> Alisyn: AND THAT WAS
SCRATCHING THE SURFACE, THOSE
WERE THE MOST DRAMATIC ORDER
OF MAGNITUDE SHOOTINGS, BUT I
HAVE A LIST HERE SINCE 1996
WHERE IT STARTED IN MOSES
LAKE, WASHINGTONS ONLY WENT
BACK TO 1996.
>> Dave: BEFORE COLUMBINE.
>> Alisyn: AND TEN SCHOOL
SHOOTINGS HAPPENED BEFORE
COLUMBINE, AND ROUGH COUNT 59
IN THE UNITED STATES.
WE HAVE THE PREPONDERANCE OF
SCHOOL VIOLENCE AND SCHOOL
SHOOTINGS THOUGH THEY DO CROP
UP IN OTHER PLACES.
AT SOME POINT SOON, WE ALL
NEED TO, AS A COUNTRY, HAVE A
REAL DIALOG AS ADULTS, AN OPEN
DIALOG, EVERYBODY WHO HAS A
DISCUSSION AND NEEDS TO BE
ABLE TO TALK ABOUT IT.
>> Dave: EVERYTHING ON THE
TABLE.
FROM THE DEPTHS OF TRAGEDY,
ONE TEACHER HID HER STUDENTS
AND ENDED UP LOSING HER OWN
LIFE.
HER INCREDIBLE STORY IS NEXT.
♪
...and this,
dancing in their heads...
...we have these.
Home Depot gift cards.
Give the gift of doing,
in-store or online.
MAYBE YOU WANT
TO INCORPORATE A BUSINESS.
ORROTECT YOUR FAMILY
WITH A WILL OR LIVING TRUST.
AND YOU'D LIKE THE HELP
OF AN ATTORNEY.
AT LEGALZOOM A LEGAL PLAN
ATTORNEY IS AVAILABLE
IN MOST STATES WITH EVERY
PERSONALIZED DOCUMENT
TO ANSWER QUESTIONS.
GET STARTED AT LEGALZOOM.COM
TODAY.
AND NOW YOU'RE PROTECTED.
I WISH I COULD KEEP IT
THIS WAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
NOW YOU CAN.
WITH THE CREST PRO-HEALTH
CLINICAL LINE.
USED TOGETHER,
THEY HELP KEEP YOUR TEETH
97% AS CLEAN
AS A DENTAL CLEANING.
THE TOOTHPASTE
ACTUALLY REDUCES PLAQUE.
AND THE RINSE REACHES ALL AREAS
AND IS CLINICALLY PROVEN TO
HELP PREVENT PLAQUE REGROWTH.
CREST PRO-HEALTH CLINICAL LINE.
TOGETHER, THEY HELP KEEP
YOUR TEETH
97% AS CLEAN
AS A DENTAL CLEANING.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
♪
ALL THE STUDENTS AT SANDY HOOK
WERE SIX AND SEVEN YEARS OLD.
AND LAST NIGHT YOU HIGGED YOUR
KIDS AND DID SO ALL NIGHT AND
WE APPRECIATE APPRECIATE THE
TEACHERS THAT TEACH OUR KIDS,
THEY DO IT NOT FOR MONEY, NOT
FOR FAME, BUT PRIMARILY THE
KIDS.
>> Kelly: AND ALSO THEY HAVE
AN ADDED RESPONSIBILITY IN
THIS DAY AND TIME.
>> Dave: AND THEY KNOW IT.
>> Kelly: THEY HAVE TO PROTECT
THE CHILDREN AT ALL TYPES AND
MY WIFE IS AN EARLY CHILD
TEACHERS AND SHE'S ENCOUNTERED
SITUATIONS WHERE SHE HAS TO BE
EXTREMELY VOCAL AND VIGILANT
AND PROVIDE SECURITY AND
SOMETIMES BEING CRITICIZED FOR
TAKING STEPS TO PROVIDE THAT
SECURITY.
>> Alisyn: THAT MAY NOT HAVE
BEEN WHAT THEY SIGNED UP
ORIGINALLY AND THAT'S WHAT
THEY DO.
VICTORIA SOTO, A 27-YEAR-OLD
TEACHER AND EXHIBIT A.
SO MANY WHAT WEEM ARE TALKING
ABOUT AS A HERO TEACHER.
THE DETAILS ARE VAGUE, BUT DID
SOMETHING IN HER CLASSROOM
THAT SPARED THE LIVES OF HER
FIRST GRADERS AND SOME REPORTS
THAT SHE HID THEM IN A CLOSET
AND THE GUNMAN CONFRONTED HER
AS SHE TOLD THEM THEY WENT
DOWN TO THE LIBRARY, THEY'RE
NOT HERE ANYMORE AND SHE
PROVIDED COVER AND HE KILLED
HER.
AND THAT'S ONE OF THE STORIES
AND THE OTHER SHE USED HER OWN
BODY AS A HUMAN SHIELD AGAINST
THE KIDS.
WE DON'T KNOW THE KIDS ARE
AGAIN, SIX AND SEVEN YEARS OLD
AND THE DETAILS ARE COMING OUT
VERY SLOWLY, BUT SHE DID
SOMETHING THAT EVERYONE IN THE
TOWN IS CELEBRATING.
>> Dave: AND THEIR UNFORTUNATE
LINK TO THE STORY IS THE PHOTO
THAT EVERYONE HAS NOW DOUBT
SEEN WITH A WOMAN HIS
TASHGICALLY CRYING WAS HER
SISTER GILLIAN AND FAMILY AND
FRIENDS SPEAKING OUT ABOUT THE
WONDERFUL 27-YEAR-OLD TEACHER
THAT WAS LOST.
>> I DIDN'T KNOW HER, BUT I'M
A MOM MYSELF AND IT COULD HAVE
BEEN MY KIDS AND WHAT SHE DID
A VERY, VERY--
THE PAIN, HOW THOSE MOTHERS
MUST BE FEELING AT THIS TIME,
A CHILD AND I COULDN'T PICTURE
THAT, YESTERDAY SHE SAVED THE
KIDS' LIFE.
>> I JUST HOPE THAT SHE'S IN A
BETTER PLACE AND SHE DIED A
HERO.
>> THAT'S AN AMAZING STORY OF
HEROISM ON BEHALF OF THIS
TEACHER AND THE PRESIDENT HAVE
TALKED ABOUT IT AND OTHERS
TALKING ABOUT THE SCRIPTURE
SAYS GREATER LOVE HAS NO MAN
THAN TO LAY DOWN HIS LIFE FOR
FELLOW MAN.
AND SHE DID THIS AND A VIGIL
IN HER HONOR, CERTAINLY NOT--
WE WOULD LOVE FOR HER TO BE
HERE, AND SHE MADE THE
ULTIMATE SACRIFICE.
AS WE TALK ABOUT SANDY HOOK
RECENTLY HAULING NEW SECURITY
MEASURES, THEY DID.
IT WAS TWO YEARS OLD, THAT'S
HOW NEW IT WAS AND THE DRILLS
ALWAYS WENT ON AND SO, WAS IN
PLACE MONTHS BEFORE THIS
TRAGEDY.
>> Alisyn: SO CAN YOU EVER
PROTECT AND DEFEND THE SCHOOL
AGAINST A HORRIFIC ACT OF
VIOLENCE LIKE THIS?
>> LET'S ASK KEN, THE
PRESIDENT OF NATIONAL SCHOOL
SAFETY AND SECURITY SERVICES,
GOOD MORNING TO YOU, KEN.
>> GOOD MORNING.
>> Dave: DID THIS--
APOLOGIES.
DID THIS SCHOOL, SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY, IT APPEARS THAT
THEY DID EVERYTHING THEY COULD
TO PROTECT ALL OF THE STUDENTS
THERE.
>> BASED ON THE INITIAL
INFORMATION WE HAVE, THEY HAD
ACCESS, CONTROL TO THE
BUILDING.
AND LOCKDOWN PROCEDURES AND
TEACHERS WHO WERE TRAINED.
THERE WERE A NUMBER OF THINGS
THAT WE TEACH AS BEST
PRACTICES IN EMERGENCY
PLANNING THAT APPEARED TO BE
IN PLACE AND PARENTS WANT TO
KNOW TWO THINGS, NUMBER ONE,
WHAT DID YOU HAVE IN PLACE,
AND HOW WELL PREPARED ARE YOU
TO PREVENT A CRISIS SITUATION
AND RESPOND TO IT, IF IT STILL
OCCURS AND UNFORTUNATELY, SOME
OF THESE INCIDENTS ARE STILL
GOING TO OCCUR.
>> Alisyn: KEN, YOU KNOW, I'VE
HEARD PEOPLE SAY THAT OVER THE
PAST 48 HOURS AND IT SOUNDS A
LITTLE DEFEATIST, I DON'T KNOW
IF YOU FEEL THE SAME WAY.
WELL, IF SOMEBODY IS EVIL OR
HELL BENT ON KILLING PEOPLE,
THERE'S NOTHING YOU CAN DO.
I'M SURE AS A SCHOOL SAFETY
EXPERT YOU MUST THINK THAT
CONCRETE STEPS THAT EVERYONE
SHOULD DO AND MAYBE THEY COULD
THWART THIS?
>> AND WE HAVE TO TRY.
I'M THE FATHER OF TWO
ELEMENTARY KIDS AND AS A
FATHER, I WANT 100% GUARANTEE
THAT MY KID'S GOING TO BE
SAFE.
AS A SCHOOL SAFETY
PROFESSIONAL, I KNOW WE CAN'T
GET TO 100% GUARANTEE, BUT WE
NEED TO TRY TO GET AS CLOSE AS
WE CAN.
WE'VE TRAINED SCHOOL
OFFICIALS.
THEY HAVE BASIC SECURITY
MEASURES AT LEAST, REDUCING
ACCESS, SCREENING AND
CHALLENGING STRANGERS, HAVING
CRISIS TEAMS, WORKING WITH LAW
ENFORCEMENT ON ACTIVE SHOOTER
TRAINING AND MAKING SURE THAT
YOU HAVE LACKDOWN DRILLS AND
EVACUATION PROCEDURES AND BE
FAMILIAR WITH THE SITUATIONS
WITH PARENTS AND EMPLOYEES,
THAT MAY SPILL OVER INTO THE
SCHOOLS.
BUT I THINK THE REAL PROBLEM
WE FACE TODAY, IS WE HAVE SOME
SERIOUS, UNDIAGNOSED AND
UNTREATED MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES
IN OUR SOCIETY AND IT'S
EXTREMELY WITH THESE LONE WOLF
FACTORS AS WE KNOW FROM THE
SHOOTINGS IN THE MALLS AND
THEATERS ELSEWHERE, WHEN IT
COULD CROSS YOUR SCHOOLHOUSE
DOORS.
>> Kelly: YOU LOOK AT THE
SITUATION WITH SANDY HOOK AND
WE KNOW BASED ON REPORTS THAT
THE PRINCIPAL OF THIS SCHOOL
WAS VERY, VERY ADAMANT ABOUT
HAVING SECURITY IN PLACE, SO
MUCH AS TO ACTUALLY CARRY OUT
DRILLS IN TERMS OF HOW TO
RESPOND AND WHAT TO DO IN CASE
OF THE EMERGENCY AND THAT
MIGHT HAVE BEEN THE VERY THING
THAT ACTUALLY SAVED SOME
ADDITIONAL LIVES, THERE ARE
REPORTS THAT WHEN THIS SHOOTER
FORCIBLY MADE HIS WAY INTO THE
SCHOOL BUILDING, A JANITOR RAN
THROUGHOUT THE SCHOOL ALERTING
PEOPLE AND SOMEONE HAD THE
SENSE TO TURN ON THE INTERCOM
SO THAT THE KIDS AP THE
TEACHERS THROUGHOUT THE SCHOOL
COULD ACTUALLY HEAR PROFANITY
AND CURSING, KNOWING THAT
SOMETHING DISTURBING WAS
UNFOLDING.
SO, ALL THE SECURITY MEASURES
WERE IN PLACE SO WHAT ELSE
COULD HAVE BEEN DONE?
>> WELL, WE'LL SEE IN THE
UPCOMING DAYS IF WE GET
ADDITIONAL INFORMATION TO SHOW
THERE ARE OTHER THINGS THAT
MIGHT HAVE BEEN DONE AND IF WE
LOSE ONE KID, IT'S ONE TOO
MANY.
I THINK THAT THE CRISIS
PLANNING PROCEDURES NA YOU
DESCRIBED, KELLY, AND THE FACT
THAT THE PRINCIPAL AND THE
PSYCHOLOGIST REPORTEDLY RAN TO
THE GUNMAN, CHARGED THE GUNMAN
SPEAKS UNBELIEVABLE AMOUNTS
ABOUT OUR EDUCATORS THAT ARE
WILLING TO PUT THEIR LIVES ON
THE THE LINE.
I THINK THAT WE HAVE TO HAVE
THE PROCEDURES IN PLACE.
WE TRAIN SCHOOL EMPLOYEES TO
DO THE DRILLS AND TO DIVERSIFY
THOSE FOR THINGS SO THAT
YOU'RE JUST NOT TRAINED TO
FOLLOW A SCRIPT, BUT MOST OF
ALL, DOWN TO THE DILIGENCE,
DETERMINATION OF THE ADULTS TO
PROTECT THEIR KIDS AND I'M NOT
SURE THAT WE COULD HAVE HEARD
OF ANY MORE DILIGENCE THAN
WHAT WE HEARD HERE IN THE LAST
FEW DAYS.
>> Alisyn: YOU'RE SO RIGHT.
KEN, IT SOUNDS LIKE EVERYONE
HERE AT SANDY HOOK DID EXACTLY
WHAT THEY WERE TRAINED TO DO.
THANKS FOR ALL OF THE TIPS
TODAY, AND THOSE ARE ALL
INTERESTING.
YOU OF COURSE ARE THE
PRESIDENT OF NATIONAL SAFETY
AND SECURITY SYSTEMS.
THANKS.
>> IT'S VERY FRUSTRATING, ALI,
THANK YOU.
>> Dave: ALL RIGHT, COMING UP
INSIDE THE MIND OF A MASS
MURDERER.
WHAT COULD CAUSE SOMEONE TO
KILL.
DR. KEITH ABLOW HERE NEXT.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN IT COMES TO
THE FINANCIAL OBSTACLES
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAN
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
I HAD[ Designer ]EELING
ENOUGH OF JUST COVERING UP
MY MODERATE TO SEVERE
PLAQUE PSORIASIS.
I DECIDED ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
♪
[ Spa Lady ]
I STARTED ENBREL.
IT'S CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO PROVIDE CLEARER SKIN.
[ RV Guy ] ENBREL MAY NOT WORK
FOR EVERYONE --
AND MAY NOT CLEAR YOU
COMPLETELY,
BUT FOR MANY, IT GETS SKIN
CLEARER FAST, WITHIN 2 MONTHS,
AND KEEPS IT CLEARER
UP TO 9 MONTHS.
[ Male Announcer ]
BECAUSE ENBREL®, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL,
EVENTS INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS, LYMPHOMA,
OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING ENBREL,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START ENBREL IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON ENBREL, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING,
OR PALENESS.
IF YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH, ASK
YOUR DERMATOLOGIST ABOUT ENBREL.
Music: "Make Someone Happy"
♪It's so important to make
someone happy.♪
Music: "Make Someone Happy"
♪'s so important to make
meone happy.♪
♪Make just one heart to heart
you - you sing to♪
♪One smile that cheers you
♪One face that lights when it
nears you.♪
♪And you will be happy too.
>>  WELCOME BACK.
AUTHORITIES STILL HAVE NO CLUE
AS TO A MOTIVE.
AS TO WHY A 20-YEAR-OLD WENT
INTO SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, SHOT AND KILLED 20
CHILDREN.
BUT THEY SAY THEY HAVE GOOD
EVIDENCE FOR WHAT CAUSES
SOMEONE TO COMMIT A MASS
MURDER.
PSYCHOLOGIST AND MEMBER OF THE
FOX NEWS MEDICAL A-TEAM, DR.
KEITH ABLOW JOINS US THIS
MORNING FROM BOSTON.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU, DOCTOR.
>> GOOD MORNING, GOOD MORNING,
HOW ARE YOU.
>> Dave: WE DON'T KNOW A WHOLE
LOT ABOUT THIS 20-YEAR-OLD.
WHAT COULD HAVE BEEN IN HIS
PAST THAT COULD AT ALL SCRATCH
THE SURFACE TO EXPLAIN THE
HORRIFIC SHOOTING ON FRIDAY?
>> WE DON'T KNOW A LOT, BUT WE
DO KNOW THAT HE HAD A
DIAGNOSIS OF SOME KIND,
WHETHER IT'S ASPERGER'S
SYNDROME OR SOMETHING ELSE, OR
WHETHER THIS WAS A
MISDIAGNOSIS NEEDS TO BE
ESTABLISHED.
IT ALSO HAS TO BE UNDERSTOOD
WHY HE WOULD HAVE BEEN GIVEN
FIREARMS BY A MOTHER WHO
DIDN'T SAFEGUARD THOSE
FIREARMS FROM HER DISTURBED
SON AND WHO REMOVED HIM FROM
THE SCHOOL BECAUSE SHE FELT HE
WASN'T WELL-SERVED THERE.
WHAT WAS THAT?
WAS THAT HER COMMANDEERING HIS
EXISTENCE OR SERVING HIM IN A
SPECIAL WAY?
WHAT WERE THE INJURIES EARLY
ON PSYCHOLOGICALLY THAT LED
THIS YOUNG MAN TO THEN LEAVE
SUCH HORRIBLE EVIDENCE OF WHAT
I PRESUME TO BE HIS OWN
INTERNAL SENSE OF HAVING BEEN
DESTROYED?
I THINK THAT'S WHAT WE MAY
SEE.
WE ALSO SEE EVIDENCE OF A
MENTAL HEALTH CARE SYSTEM IN
UTTER DISARRAY HERE, BECAUSE
THAT'S WHAT OUR MENTAL HEALTH
CARE SYSTEM IS, COMPLETELY
UNRELIABLE, UNDERSTAFFED, TOO
LITTLE EXPERTISE, NOT KNOWING
WHICH WAY TO TURN WITH SOMEONE
LIKE THIS.
>> DOC, INEVITABLY THE GUN
CONTROL ARGUMENT HAS BEGUN.
I DON'T KNOW IF THERE'S ENOUGH
SAID, THE MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEM
IN THIS COUNTRY.
HOW DOES IT NEED TO CHANGE?
>> THIS HAS NOTHING TO DO, I
PROMISE THIS HAS NOTHING TO DO
WITH GUN CONTROL.
THESE WERE LEGALLY BOUGHT
FIREARMS, HELD BY A WOMEN WHO
BOUGHT THEM AT STORES, NOT GUN
SHOWS AS FAR AS I KNOW.
THE MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEM IN
AMERICA WE'VE PUSHED DOWN THE
LOWEST LEVEL THE EXPERTISE
THAT SHOULD BE HIGHEST LEVEL.
WE HAVE KIDS LIKE THIS AND
WORSE, WHO ALREADY EXPRESSING
VIOLENT FANTASIES BEING
TREATED BY NEWLY MINTED SOCIAL
WORKERS WHO HAVE NEVER BEEN
SCHOOLED IN INTROSPECTIVE
TECHNIQUES AND TRAINING, AND
WHY?
INSURANCE COMPANIES WILL PAY
ONLY THEM.
WE HAVE THEIR MEDICINES
PRESCRIBED BY NURSE
CLINICIANS.
WHY?
BECAUSE THE INSURANCE COMPANY
WON'T PAY PSYCHIATRISTS TO DO
THAT WORK.
WE HAVE NO CONNECTION BETWEEN
OUR CRISIS AND OUR COMMUNITY
MENTAL HEALTH SYSTEMS AND OUR
POLICE, OUR JUDICIARY AND OUR
HOSPITAL.
WE HAVE PEOPLE IN E.R.'S WHO
ARE PSYCHIATRY RESIDENTS AND
PSYCHIATRISTS WHO DON'T
LITERALLY KNOW WHO TO CALL IF
THEY HAVE A PSYCHIATRIC
PATIENT COME INTO THE E.R.,
WHO IS EXPRESSING VIOLENCE
SHORT OF MURDER, BUT FOR WHOM
THEY'RE TERRIBLY CONCERNED.
WE STILL HAVE ALL KINDS OF
EXPERTS, QUOTES, UNQUOTE.
PSYCHIATRISTS AND SOCIAL
WORKERS AND OTHERS WHO BELIEVE
WHEN THEY SAY HE WON'T DO IT,
GET TO THE E.R. AFTER THEY SIT
IN A PSYCHIATRIST'S OFFICE I
DO INTEND TO HARM PEOPLE AND
THEY SHOULD GO HOME BECAUSE
THEY'RE QUOTE, UNQUOTE,
CONTRACTED FOR SAFETY AND THE
INSURANCE COMPANY WON'T PAY TO
ADMIT THEM TO THE HOSPITAL.
RIGHT NOW WE DON'T HAVE A
MENTAL HEALTH CARE SYSTEM, WE
HAVE A VARIETY OF CLINICIANS
POORLY TRAINED, NOT IN ANY WAY
INTEGRATED WITH NO MARCHING
ORDERS WITH WHAT TO DO WITH
THE POTENTIALLY VIOLENTLY ILL.
>> MYSELF A PARENT OF THREE,
I'M ASTOUNDED, TIME AND TIME
AGAIN, THE PARENTS ARE MISSING
OBVIOUS WARNING SIGNS AND ONE
OF THEM MAY BE THE VIOLENT
VIDEO GAMES WE'VE HEARD SO
MUCH ABOUT.
I'VE MENTIONED THAT I WAS
COVERING THE COLUMBINE
SHOOTING MANY, MANY YEARS AGO.
AND THOSE TWO SHOOTSERS WERE
PLAYING SOME OF VIOLENT VIDEO
GAMES THAT HAVE FAR EVOLVED
OVER THE YEARS AND WE'VE HEARD
ABOUT IN LATEST SHOOTER,
HAVING PLAYED SOME FANTASY
WEAPON RELATED VIDEO GAMES,
HOW BIG A PROBLEM ARE THEY?
AND WHAT DO PARENTS NEED TO
KNOW?
>> I THINK THE WHOLE
WATERFRONT HAS TO BE LOOKED AT
HERE, FROM VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES
TO THE DESENSETIZATION OF
PEOPLE THROUGH EVERYTHING FROM
FACEBOOK, WHERE YOU CREATE
FALSE FRIENDS AND FICTIONALIZE
YOUR PROFILE, TO OBVIOUSLY,
THESE VIDEO GAMES, BUT BEYOND
NA, LET'S LOOK AT THE WHOLE OF
THE THINGS INVOLVING
TECHNOLOGY THAT REMOVE US FROM
OUR FEELINGS, THAT DESTROY OUR
CAPACITY FOR EMPATHY AND FOR
THE FRAGILE AMONG US, IT CAN
COMPLETELY ANNIHILATE THAT
CAPACITY FOR EMPATHY AND THEN
LET'S LOOK AT THE PERSONAL.
THIS MOTHER ARMED HER
DISTURBED SON WITH WEAPONS OF
MASS DESTRUCTION, WITH THE
SEMI AUTOMATIC WEAPONS, WHAT
SHORT OF WOMAN WE SHOULD TALK
ABOUT, WE SHOULD KNOW, IS THIS
AN INTENSITY PERSONAL FAMILY
DRAMA IN WHICH A PERSON WAS
CREATED WITHOUT EMPATHY OR
SOMETHING ELSE.
>> AND WE CERTAINLY NEED TO
LOOK AT THE AGE GROUP FROM THE
LATE TEENS TO MID 20'S, THANK
YOU SO MUCH FOR YOUR INSIGHT
THIS MORNING, WE APPRECIATE
IT.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> RIGHT BACK WITH THE SPECIAL
COVERAGE OF THIS TRAGIC
SHOOTING WHEN "FOX & FRIENDS"
CONTINUES.
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
e Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a
Droid Incredible 4G LTE
by HTC for $49.99.
>>  WELCOME BACK EVERYONE, YOU
JUST HEARD KEITH ABLOW, DR.
KEITH ABLOW TALKING ABOUT THE
THE GUNMAN'S MOTHER.
WE KNOW THAT SHE WAS A GUN
ENTHUSIAST AND SHE WAS A GUN
COLLECTOR.
SHE HAD GUNS IN HER HOME AND
THERE ARE REPORTS THAT SHE
TOOK HER SON TO THE SHOOTING
RANGE AND HELPED TRAIN HIM TO
SHOOT.
THERE ARE OTHER REPORTS, TO
FLESH OUT THE PICTURE OF THIS
MAN FROM FAMILY MEMBERS WHO
SAID SHE WAS AN INCREDIBLY
DEDICATED LOVING MOTHER THAT
SHE WOULD SACRIFICE ANYTHING
FOR HER CHILDREN, WHEN THE
PUBLIC SCHOOL WASN'T WORKING
OUT FOR HER SON SHE TOOK HIM
OUT AND HOME SCHOOLED HIM FOR
A LARGE PART OF HIGH SCHOOL.
>> IT'S SO HARD TO BELIEVE AND
POLICE ARE LOOKING INTO IT TO
FIND OUT WHY ADAM LANZA WOULD
TAKE ONE OF THE WEAPONS HIS
MOTHER PURCHASED AND USE IT
AGAINST HIS MOTHER AND REPORTS
ARE HE SHOT HER IN THE FACE
AND NEN LEFT HER AND WENT TO
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
WHERE THE CARNAGE UNFOLDED AND
THE FAMILY IS SPEAKING ABOUT
IT AND WE MUST POINT OUT THE
MOM AND DAD WERE DIVORCED IN
2009.
THE FATHER HAS BEEN SPEAKING
OUT AND ISSUED A STATEMENT
WITH REGARD TO THIS TRAGEDY,
EXPRESSING WHAT THE FAMILY IS
GOING THROUGH.
BUT LET'S LISTEN TO MARSHA
LANZA RIGHT NOW.
>> NICE KID, GOOD KID AND
CHALLENGES IN THE FAMILY IN
HOUSE, WHEN THEY HAVE ONE, I
HAVE ONE, BUT NEVER IN TROUBLE
WITH THE LAW, NEVER IN TROUBLE
WITH ANYTHING.
I KNOW SHE HAD ISSUES WITH
SCHOOL.
SHE MENTIONED HOME SCHOOLING
HIM AND SHE BATTLED THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT AND WHAT, TO NOT 100%
CERTAIN IF IT WAS BEHAVIOR OR
LEARNING DISABILITIES, I DON'T
KNOW, HE'S A VERY, VERY BRIGHT
BOY.
IF SHE DID SHE WOULDN'T HAVE
TOLERATED IT.
IF HE NEEDED HELP SHE WOULD
HAVE GOTTEN.
EVEN WHEN THEY WERE MARRIED,
AND IF THE KIDS HAD A NEED,
THEY WOULD DEFINITELY FILL IT.
>> Dave: AND THAT PHRASE
THERE, BATTLE WITH THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT, WHY?
WAS IT BECAUSE AS REPORTED THE
CHILD HAD ASPERGER'S, THEY
COULDN'T FIND HELP FOR HIM OR
BEHAVIOR.
AND WHY HAVE THREE GUNS AND
YOUR CHILD ACCESS TO THEM,
WHEN THEY'RE CLEARLY NOT
HUNTING TYPES.
>> Alisyn: WE'LL READ THE
FATHER'S STATEMENT AS WELL AND
WE'LL TALK TO A GOOD FRIEND OF
THE SANDY HOOK PRINCIPAL,
TRAGICALLY KILLED.
WHO SHE WAS, HOW MUCH SHE
LOVED HER STUDENTS NEXT.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
JILL AND HER MOUTH HAVE LIVED
A GREAT LIFE.
BUT SHE HAS SOME DENTAL ISSUES
SHE'S NOT HAPPY ABOUT.
SO I INTRODUCED JILL
TO CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SELECTED FOR PEOPLE OVER 50.
PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE IS A
TOOTHPASTE THAT DEFENDS AGAINST
TENDER, INFLAMED GUMS,
SENSITIVITY AND WEAK ENAMEL.
CONDITIONS PEOPLE OVER 50
EXPERIENCE.
CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SO JILL CAN KEEP LIVING
THE GOOD LIFE.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
But when I was in an accident...
SO JILL CAN KEEP LIVING
THE GOOD LIFE.
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
So I never missed a beat.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.
>>  GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE,
IT'S SUNDAY, DECEMBER 16TH.
I'M ALISYN CAMEROTA.
AS THE COUNTRY MOURNING WE'RE
LEARNING THE NAMES OF THE
LITTLE ONES IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WILL WE EVER GET ANSWERS AS TO
WHY THIS ALL HAPPENED.
>> Dave: AND A MOURNING FATHER
PUTS ON A BRAVE FACE TO SHARE
THE MEMORIES OF HIS LITTLE
GIRL LOST.
>> SHE WAS THE TYPE OF PERSON
THAT COULD JUST LIGHT UP A
ROOM.
SHE -- SHE ALWAYS HAD
SOMETHING KIND TO SAY ABOUT
ANYBODY, THE LOVE AND STRENGTH
SHE GAVE US AND THE EXAMPLE
SHE SHOWED US IS REMARKABLE.
>> Dave: AN INCREDIBLE MESSAGE
OF FORGIVENESS IS COMING UP.
>> Kelly: AND THE STORIES OF
HEROES EMERGING FROM THIS
TRAGEDY.
A PRINCIPAL SO DEDICATED, SHE
RAN TOWARDS THE GUNMAN, TRYING
TO SAVE STUDENTS.
A FRIEND OF DAWN HOCHSPRUNG
JOINS US THIS HOUR.
"FOX & FRIENDS" STARTS RIGHT
NOW.
>> .
>> Kelly: WELCOME BACK,
EVERYBODY, THANKS FOR JOINING
US.
OBVIOUSLY IT'S WITH HEAVY
HEARTS THAT WE'RE ALL HERE
THIS MORNING AND WE KNOW FROM
ALL OF YOU, COMMUNICATING WITH
US, VIA TWITTER THAT THE WHOLE
COUNTRY IS DEVASTATED AND
PEOPLE SAY THAT THEY CAN'T
STOP CRYING AND WE CERTAINLY
KNOW THE FEELING AND KELLY
WRIGHT IT'S GREAT TO HAVE NEW
FOR CLAYTON TODAY.
>> Kelly: I WISH I WAS HERE
UNDER BETTER CIRCUMSTANCES,
BUT IT'S GOOD TO BE WITH YOU.
>> Dave: THE PRESIDENT WILL
PAY A VISIT TO NEWTOWN TONIGHT
FOR A SPECIAL CANDLELIGHT
VIGIL AND UNFORTUNATELY THE
FOURTH VISIT TO THE SITE AFTER
MASS SHOOTING FROM THE
PRESIDENT.
NOW THE THE MOURNER IN CHIEF
ALL TOO FAMILIAR A ROLE FOR
PRESIDENT OBAMA.
>> Kelly: IT'S VERY DIFFICULT
FOR HIM AS WE'VE SEEN FROM
FRIDAY AND SATURDAY.
IT'S DIFFICULT FOR ALL OF US
AS THE NATION MOURNS.
>> Alisyn: JUST WHEN YOU THINK
THAT YOU CAN'T HEAR ANY MORE
INFORMATION THAT WILL RACK YOU
AGAIN WITH GRIEF, THE NAMES OF
THE VICTIMS AND THEIR AGES HAS
BEEN RELEASED AND JUST LOOKING
THROUGH THE PIECE OF PAPER.
EVEN IF YOU DON'T KNOW THEM
PERSONALLY, SEE THEIR TENDER
AGES WAS SHOCKING.
THERE WERE 20 CHILDREN KILLED,
AS YOU KNOW, AND ALL OF THEM
WERE SIX AND SEVEN YEARS OLD.
AND OF COURSE, THERE WERE SIX
ADULTS, ALSO, KILLED ALT THE
SCHOOL AND ALL OF THOSE WERE
WOMEN.
>> Dave: AS FOR THOSE
STUDENTS, 12 WERE GIRLS, EIGHT
WERE BOYS.
ALL WERE SHOT MORE THAN ONCE,
THESE CHILDREN, SOME WERE SHOT
11 TIMES, CLEARLY AT CLOSE
ROUNDING AND AGAIN, ALL OF
THESE KIDS, SIX AND SEVEN
YEARS OLD, FIRST GRADE
CHILDREN.
>> Kelly: IT'S HARD TO FATHOM
THIS AND UNIMAGINABLE AND WE
ALSO UNDERSTAND THROUGH
REPORTS AND POLICE COMING OUT
AND GIVING US DETAILS OF ADAM
LANZA HAVING ACCESS TO GUNS
THAT HIS MOTHER OWNED AND WE
SHOULD MENTION THAT THESE WERE
HIGH TARGET GUNS, HIGH QUALITY
GUNS.
>> Alisyn: SEMI AUTOMATICS.
>> Kelly: AND POLICE USE THESE
WEAPONS AND SECRET SERVICE HAD
THE WEAPONS AND HIS MOTHER
NANCY WAS A COLLECTOR OF THESE
GUNS AND TAUGHT HER SON HOW TO
SHOOT.
AND NOTHING WRONG WITH THAT,
PEOPLE TRAIN EACH OTHER TO USE
THE GUNS AND MAY FIND IT AS A
SPORT, BUT THIS WAS A TERRIBLE
SCENE THAT PERHAPS NO ONE SAW
AND POLICE ARE PUTTING
TOGETHER THE EVIDENCE TO FIND
OUT WHAT MAY HAVE LED TO THIS.
>> Alisyn: AND IT'S JUST MORE
COMPLICATED BECAUSE WE NOW
KNOW THAT THE SHOOTER HAD
ASPERGER'S SYNDROME, WHICH IS
A SPECTRUM OF AUTISM AND NO
ONE KNOWS IT'S LINKED TO
VIOLENCE NO HISTORY OF LEADING
TO VIOLENCE, BUT HIS BROTHER
SAID A PERSONALITY DISORDER
AND WHY EYEBROWS WERE RAISED
WHY HE WOULD HAVE BEEN TAKEN
WITH HER TO THE SHOOTING RANGE
AND ACCORDING TO THE NEW YORK
POST SHE REGULARLY TOOK HIM TO
THE SHOOTING RANGE.
AND ALL OF THESE ANSWERS HAVE
TO COME OUT, BUT PEOPLE SAY
THAT NANCY LANZA, THE FIRST
VICTIM, WAS INCREDIBLY
DEDICATED MOTHER AND MADE
SACRIFICES FOR HER SON AND
OTHER SON.
>> Dave: AS WE LEARN MORE
ABOUT THE VICTIMS OF THIS
TRAGEDY AND EMOTIONAL VICTIMS
HONORING THEIR MEMORY
CONTINUE.
>> AND THE LOSS NO REALLY
WORDS TO DESCRIBE THAT,
NOTHING YOU CAN SAY TO THEM TO
CONSOLE THEM, IT'S JUST, IT'S
JUST SOMETHING LOST FOREVER.
>> AND THE VIGILS CONTINUE
THROUGH THE NIGHT AND THROUGH
THE WEEK AND CONNECTICUT AND
CERTAINLY THE COUNTRY AS WELL.
AND PETER DOOCY LIVE WITH MORE
FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU, PETER.
>> Reporter:  GOOD MORNING,
DAVE.
AND WE JUST GOT WORD IN THE
LAST HOUR OR SO THAT AN
ANONYMOUS PERSON FROM NORTH
CAROLINA HAS DONATED 26
CHRISTMAS TREES, THAT'S ONE
FOR EACH STUDENTS AND EACH
TEACHER KILLED INSIDE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND
THEY'RE SET UP ON THE ROAD TO
THE SITE OF THAT TERRIBLE RUN,
DICKENSON IN SANDY HOOK, IN
NEWTOWN, ACCORDING TO THE
LOCAL NEWSPAPER, ONE OF THE
WAIST MANY FOLKS AROUND THE
COUNTRY ARE PAYING TRIBUTE TO
THE FALLEN AND TEACHERS AND
DOAN ARE OF THE CHRISTMAS
TREES OF NORTH CAROLINA, UP
THE STREET.
A GROUP OF STUDENTS WHO WAS IN
THE SCHOOL WHEN THE SHOOTING
STARTED, SETS UP A YARD SALE
WHERE THEY WERE SELLING THEIR
TOYS TO PASSERSBY, TRYING TO
RAISE MONEY FOR THEIR AFFECTED
CLASSMATES AND NEIGHBORS.
MANY, MANY OTHER FOLKS HAVE
BEEN LIGHTING CANDLES AND
SAYING PRAYERS AND ATTENDING
VIGILS, A VERY TOUCHING ONE A
FEW TOWNS OVER FOR THE
27-YEAR-OLD TEACHER WHO DIED
TRYING TO SAVE HER STUDENTS,
VICTORIA SOTO.
>> THE PAIN, HOW THOSE MOTHERS
MUST BE FEELING AT THIS TIME.
NOT ONLY CHILD, BUT I COULDN'T
PICTURE THAT, AND THAT'S WHY
I'M HERE TODAY.
BECAUSE SHE SAVED A LOT OF
KIDS LIVES.
>> THE MOTHER OF THE STUDENTS
WHO SAW MISS SOTO GET SHOT,
TOLD ME LAST NIGHT SHE STILL
HAS NOT TOLD HER SON ABOUT HIS
DAUGHTER'S FATE BECAUSE SHE
SAYS HE LOVED HIS TEACHER,
MISS SOTO AND HE'S ALREADY
DEALT WITH A LOT THIS WEEK.
THE PRESIDENT IS GOING TO BE
HERE LATER ON TODAY FOR AN
INTERFAITH VIGIL AT NEWTOWN
HIGH SCHOOL.
AND THE CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR
HAS BEEN HERE EVERY DAY
COMFORTING HIS HEART BROKEN
NEIGHBORS.
>> WE CAN SPEAK ABOUT WHAT'S
REALLY IMPORTANT AND WHAT CAN
WAIT FOR ANOTHER DAY.
THERE WILL BE TIME SOON FOR A
DISCUSSION OF PUBLIC POLICY
ISSUES SURROUNDING YESTERDAY'S
EVENTS.
BUT WHAT'S IMPORTANT RIGHT NOW
IS LOVE, COURAGE, AND
COMPASSION.
LOVE AS IT HAS POURED IN FROM
AROUND THE WORLD.
>> GRIEF COUNSELORS FROM
THROUGHOUT NEW ENGLAND HAVE
DESCENDED ON NEWTOWN AT A
SCHOOL NEARBY, FROM SEVEN TO
SEVEN TODAY, COUNSELING WILL
BE CONTINUE AND WE'VE BEEN
TOLD A LOT OF FOLKS AROUND THE
AREA HAVE BEEN TAKING
ADVANTAGE OF THOSE SERVICES.
BACK TO YOU IN NEW YORK.
>> Alisyn: THANKS SO MUCH,
PETER.
WE APPRECIATE THE UPDATE.
WE HAVEN'T HEARD FROM THE
FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS,
OBVIOUSLY, TOO OVERWHELMED
WITH GRIEF TO SPEAK OUT IF
THEY EVER WILL, BUT A COUPLE
HAVE AND WHAT ONE FATHER HAS
COME OUT TO SAY HAS BEEN
BEYOND INSPIRATIONAL IN TERMS
OF HIS STRENGTH.
ROBBIE PARKER IS THE FATHER OF
ONE OF THE YOUNGEST VICTIMS,
HER NAME EMILIE PARKER, SIX
YEARS OLD AND HE CAME OUT TO
TALK ABOUT HIS DAUGHTER AND
THE COMPASSION HE FEELS FOR
THE SHOOTER'S FAMILY.
>> FIRST OF ALL, I'D REALLY
LIKE TO OFFER OUR DEEPEST TO
ALL THE FAMILIES WHO WERE
DIRECTLY AFFECTED BY THIS
SHOOTING.
IT'S A HORRIFIC TRAGEDY AND WE
WANTED EVERYBODY TO KNOW THAT
OUR HEARTS AND OUR PRAYERS GO
OUT TO THEM.
THIS INCLUDES THE FAMILY OF
THE SHOOTER.
I CAN'T IMAGINE HOW HARD THIS
EXPERIENCE MUST BE FOR YOU.
AND I WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT
OUR FAMILY AND OUR LOVE AND
OUR SUPPORT GO OUT TO YOU AS
WELL.
MY DAUGHTER EMILIE WOULD BE
ONE OF THE FIRST ONES TO BE
STANDING AND GIVING HER LOVE
AND SUPPORT TO THOSE VICTIMS
BECAUSE THAT'S THE TYPE OF
PERSON THAT SHE IS.
NOT BECAUSE OF ANY PARENTING
THAT MY WIFE AND I HAVE DONE,
BUT BECAUSE THOSE WERE THE
GIFTS GIVEN TO HER BY HER
HEAVENLY FATHER.
>> Kelly: YOU KNOW, WHEN YOU
HEAR THAT, YOU THINK HOW IS IT
POSSIBLE THAT A MAN WHO HAS
LOST HIS OLDEST DAUGHTER.
HE HAS THREE DAUGHTERS, ALL
UNDER THE AGE OF SIX, EMILIE
THE OLDEST AND TAKE HER OFF TO
SCHOOL AND YOU CAN'T GET BACK
TO HER.
YOU'RE POWERLESS, YOU'RE
HOPELESS AND WITHOUT HOPE AND
YET, THIS MAN TALKS ABOUT AN
AMAZING, AN AMAZING GRACE AND
FORGIVENESS, IT'S UNTHINKABLE
IN SUCH A TRAGEDY, BUT YET,
THIS MAN HAS TAPPED INTO
SOMETHING THAT MANY PEOPLE
WILL HAVE TO TRY TO FIND.
THEY'LL HAVE TO TRY THE POWER.
>> Dave: NOT SURE I COULD.
>> Kelly: AND YOU HAVE TO
UNDERSTAND THIS GUY, FOR HIM,
THAT IS HIS WAY FORWARD IN
FINDING HIS RELATIONSHIP RIGHT
WITH THE WORLD, WITH GOD AND
WITH, EVEN WITH THE KILLER OF
HIS DAUGHTER.
>> Dave: AND ROBBIE,
UNFORTUNATELY DIDN'T HAVE TO,
BUT WANTED TO SPEAK OUT ABOUT
THE LAST INTERACTION HE HAD
WITH HIS WONDERFUL YOUNG
SIX-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER.
>> SHE WOKE UP BEFORE I LEFT.
AND I ACTUALLY HAD BEEN
TEACHING HER PORTUGESE AND SO
OUR LAST CONVERSATION WAS IN
PORTUGESE AND SHE TOLD ME GOOD
MORNING AND I WAS
DOING, I SAID I WAS DOING
WELL.
SHE SAITHAT SHE LOVED ME AND
I GAVE HER A KISS AND I WAS
OUT THE DOOR.
>> Alisyn: WHAT A SWEET, SWEET
FATHER.
THERE'S ANOTHER FAMILY, THAT
OF SEVEN-YEAR-OLD GRACE
MCDONNELL, THEY DIDN'T WANT TO
COME AND SPEAK PUBLICLY, BUT
PUT OUT A STATEMENT HONORING
THEIR SEVEN-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER
AND THEY SAID WE'RE
OVERWHELMED BY THE OUTPOURING
OF LOVE AND SUPPORT FOR SO
MANY PEOPLE.
OUR DAUGHTER GRACE WAS THE
LIGHT AND LOVE OUR FAMILY AND
CAN'T EXPRESS THE LOSS.
AND EVERYBODY TALKED ABOUT MOU
SHE LOOKED LIKE A LITTLE DOLL
TO PEOPLE BECAUSE SHE HAD SUCH
BEAUTIFUL DEEP BLUE EYES AND
PRETTY BLOND HAIR AND
OBVIOUSLY, HOW MUCH SHE WILL
HE' BE MISSED.
>> Dave: I HAD ON THE SHOW THE
STORIES OF HEROES EMERGING
FROM TRAGEDY, A PRINCIPAL SO
DEDICATED SHE RAN TOWARDS THE
GUNMAN TRYING TO SAVE HER
STUDENTS.
♪
...and this,
dancing in their heads...
...we have these.
Home Depot gift cards.
Give the gift of doing,
in-store or online.
PREGO?!
BUT I'VE BOUGHT RAGU FOR YEARS.
[ Thinking ] WONDER WHAT OTHER
QUESTIONABLE CHOICES I'VE MADE?
I CHOOSE DATE NUMBER 2!
WHOOO!
[ sigh of relief ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHOOSE TASTE. CHOOSE PREGO.
often comes with a set
of equally impressive
instructions ?
Shouldn't something
that's truly advanced,
not need much explanation
at all ?
With the Nokia Lumia 822
on Verizon,
there's not much to learn
because it's
powered by Windows...
to let you do more than you ever
imagined on your smartphone.
Exclusively with Data Sense--
a feature that makes
the most of your plan.
Only on Verizon.
It's hard to see opportunity
in today's challenging
environment.
Unless you have the right
perspective.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
has the vision
and experience to look beyond
the obvious.
We'll uncover opportunities,
find hidden risk,
and make success a reality.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
>>  AS DETAILS INTO FRIDAY'S
DEADLY MASSACRE CONTINUE TO
UNFOLD.
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT IS
REMEMBERING A HERO, PRINCIPAL
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG.
NOT ONLY A LOVING WIFE AND
MOTHER, BUT DEDICATED AND
PROTECTING HER STUDENTS UNTIL
THE VERY END.
>> Dave: AND GERALD IS WITH US
THIS MORNING, A CLOSE FRIEND
OF DAWN'S.
HE JOINS US LIVE THIS MORNING.
GOOD MORNING, GERALD.
NICE OF YOU TO BE WITH US THIS
MORNING.
AND TELL US ABOUT YOUR FRIEND,
THIS WONDERFUL, CARING AND
BRAVE PRINCIPAL.
>> GOOD MORNING, YES.
DAWN WAS A VERY INSPIRATIONAL
TYPE OF EDUCATOR, HER
STUDENTS, HER FRIENDS, THE
TEACHERS, THE PARENTS
ABSOLUTELY ALL ADORED HER.
>> Alisyn: GERALD, YOU KNOW,
WE JUST M A SCHOOL SAFETY
EXPERT ON LAST HOUR WHO SAID
SOMETHING I DIDN'T KNOW WHICH
WAS THAT SOME OF THE EDUCATORS
AND PRINCIPALS ARE ACTUALLY
TRAINED TO CHALLENGE AND
CONFRONT STRANGERS WHEN THEY
MAKE IT INTO THE SCHOOL.
I DIDN'T KNOW THAT THAT WAS
PART OF THEIR TRAINING AND
IT'S ONE THING TO SAY THAT
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO CONFRONT A
STRANGE, BUT WHEN THAT
STRANGER IS ARMED AND IN BLACK
RIOT GEAR, OBVIOUSLY, IT'S A
MUCH DIFFERENT THING.
SHE COULD HAVE GONE AND RUN
THE OTHER WAY AND BARRICADED
HERSELF IN HER OFFICE.
IS IT SURPRISING TO YOU THAT
SHE CONFRONTED THE GUNMAN?
>> NO, IT ISN'T.
DAWN USED TO BE A PRINCIPAL IN
OUR SCHOOL SYSTEM AND AFTER
THE COLUMBINE INCIDENT, DAWN
AND I HAD SEVERAL CONVERSATION
INS REGARDS TO THIS TYPE OF
SITUATION WITH AN ACTIVE
SHOOTER AND WE BASICALLY
PLAYED IT OUT AND HAD
DISCUSSION THE ABOUT THE
RESPONSIBILITIES OF THE
STUDENTS, THE RESPONSIBILITIES
OF THE EDUCATORS AND THE
ADMINISTRATION.
AND WE ALSO HAD FRANK
DISCUSSIONS ABOUT WHAT OUR
ROLES WOULD BE AND IT'S NO
SURPRISING THAT WE--
THAT SHE DID WHAT SHE DID.
WE ACTUALLY SORT OF PLAYED
THIS OUT ONE TIME AND IN
HAVING A REAL SHOOTER AND IT'S
NOT SURPRISING THAT IS SHE
WOULD GIVE UP HER LIFE FOR HER
STUDENTS.
>> Kelly: GERALD, WE
UNDERSTAND THAT DAWN WAS
ACTUALLY HAPPY ABOUT THE FACT
THAT SHE WAS ABLE TO BRING HER
SCHOOL INTO THE MODERN ERA OF
BEING ABLE TO BE SAFEGUARDED
AND PROTECTED, AND PUTTING ALL
THE MEASURES IN PLACE TO
ACTUALLY PROTECT HER STUDENTS,
HER TEACHERS, THE STAFF.
SHE WAS REALLY, REALLY ADAMANT
ABOUT THAT, AND PROACTIVE
ABOUT THAT.
SO, ON THIS DAY, THE FACT THAT
SHE SACRIFICED HERSELF, WHAT
IS THE COMMUNITY LOSING IN
THIS WONDERFUL LEADER WHO
INSPIRED SO MANY TEACHERS AND
STUDENTS?
>> YEAH, SHE DID TAKE THIS
VERY SERIOUSLY, LIKE I SAID,
WE HAD FRANK DISCUSSIONS AND
WE'VE TRAINED, WE'VE
PRACTICED, AND SHE KNEW THAT
THE HEALTH AND SAFETY OF HER
CHILDREN WERE ABSOLUTELY
PARAMOUNT.
I THINK THAT--
THE THING THAT WE NEED TO COME
AWAY FROM THIS WAS THE FACT
THAT SHE ACTUALLY SAVED A
GREAT MANY LIVES AND TAKE INTO
ACTIONS THAT SHE DID, THAT
SHOOTER HAD THE CAPABILITY OF
KILLING MUCH MORE IN THIS
TRAGEDY WOULD HAVE BEEN FAR
WORSE IF IT WASN'T FOR HER
HEROIC ACTIONS, SO, I THINK
THAT THAT LOSS CERTAINLY IS
EXTREMELY HEART FELT AND WE'RE
SADDENED, BUT IN THE OTHER
INSTANCE, IT GIVES ME GREAT
PLEASURE TO KNOW THAT SHE DID
WHAT SHE WAS SUPPOSED TO DO
AND WHEN WE TALK ABOUT THESE
TYPES OF THINGS, IN OUR
WILDEST DREAMS DID WE EVER
THINK THAT THE CONVERSATION
THAT HER AND I ACTUALLY HAD
WOULD UNFOLD INTO REALITY AND
THEN CAUSING THE LOSS OF HER
LIFE.
SHE'S TRULY A HERO TODAY.
>> Dave: WE MENTION YOU'RE THE
FIRST SELECTMEN IN WOODBURY
AND HOW IS YOUR COMMUNITY
COMING TOGETHER AROUND THIS
TRAGEDY?
>> THE FIRST THING WHEN THIS
WAS UNFOLDING WAS SHEER SHOCK
AND THEN IT WAS HORROR AND
THEN IT GOES INTO HEART BREAK
AND AS A COMMUNITY, WE'RE
COMING TOGETHER AND WE'RE ALL
TALKING, WE'RE GRIEVING AND
TRYING TO MAKE SOME SENSE OF
THE SENSELESS AND WE'RE
STRONG, WE'RE A SMALL
COMMUNITY AND WE'LL COME
TOGETHER AND GET THROUGH THIS.
>> Dave: IS THERE ANYTHING YOU
NEED?
I THINK SO MANY PEOPLE ASK US
WHAT CAN WE DO?
IS THERE ANYTHING THAT PEOPLE
THERE NEED FROM OUR VIEWERS
AND PEOPLE ACROSS THE COUNTRY?
>> YEAH, I THINK ASIDE FROM
YOUR THOUGHTS AND PRAYERS, I
THINK THE ONE THING THAT, AS I
SPOKE WITH DAWN WE OFTEN
TALKED ABOUT WHY PEOPLE TAKE
THIS TYPE OF ACTION AND GO
INTO SCHOOLS AND SHOOT AND
TAKE INNOCENT LIVES AND I
THINK THE THING WE NEED TO
COME AWAY WITH THIS, ONCE THIS
HAPPENS, THERE'S A GREAT DEAL
OF DISCUSSION ABOUT MENTAL
STABILITY AND A LOT OF PEOPLE
KNEW THEY WERE TROUBLED.
AND I THINK THE THING THAT
DAWN AND I TALKED ABOUT, WE
NEED TO REACH OUT TO THESE
PEOPLE AHEAD OF TIME AND NOT
TURN A BLIND EYE TO THEM,
RECOGNIZE THEIR DIFFICULTIES,
PUT A HAND OUT, AND THIS IS
THE RESPONSIBILITY OF ANY,
EVERY INDIVIDUAL IN OUR
SOCIETY.
AND I THINK IF DAWN WAS HERE,
SHE WOULD CERTAINLY BE SAYING
THE SAME THING AND I THINK
THAT'S WHAT WE REALLY NEED IS
THOUGHTS AND PRAYERS AND
CERTAINLY REACH OUT TO YOUR
NEIGHBORS.
>> GERALD, THAT'S SUCH A GREAT
REMINDER AND A NIGHTS MESSAGE,
WE TALK SO MUCH HOW DEDICATED
DAWN WAS AND A PRINCIPAL.
AND SHE ALSO HAD A FAMILY.
CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT HER
FAMILY?
>> YEAH, JUST LIKE HER
STUDENTS SHE CARED A GREAT
DEAL OF HER FAMILY AND TALKED
OFTEN OF THE FAMILY.
SHE WAS A GREAT MOTHER, A
STEPMOTHER, A WIFE AND HER
FAMILY ACTUALLY LIVES IN OUR
TOWN, AGAIN, A SMALL COMMUNITY
AND WE WOULD SEE EACH OTHER IN
THE GROCERY STORE AND I
CONTINUALLY ASKED HER TO COME
BACK AND OUR THOUGHTS AND
PRAYERS TO HER FAMILY.
>> Kelly: GERALD, BEFORE YOU
GO ON, HOW DO YOU CONTINUE AS
A COMMUNITY.
>> WE CRY A LOT, WE TALK A LOT
AND WE MOVE ON AND WE CONTINUE
AND WE LEARN FROM SOME OF THE
THINGS THAT DAWN HAS TAUGHT
US.
YOU KNOW, AGAIN, WE WORK VERY
HARD WITH OUR COMMUNITY TO TRY
TO ALLEVIATE THESE PROBLEMS
WITH THE THINGS THAT WE SAW
WITH THIS HORRIFIC TRAGEDY,
WE'RE GOING TO LEARN FROM THIS
AND GOING TO BRING THIS BACK
TO OUR COMMUNITY AND TAKE
STEPS TO MAKE SURE THIS
DOESN'T HAPPEN AGAIN.
>> Alisyn: GERALD, THANKS SO
MUCH FOR SHARING YOUR PERSONAL
REMEMBRANCES OF YOUR GOOD
FRIEND DAWN, WE APPRECIATE IT.
>> GREAT, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
HAVE A GOOD DAY.
>> Dave: COMING UP, AS THE
NATION MOURNS FRIDAY'S
UNTHINKABLE TRAGEDY, THE
NEWTOWN COMMUNITY IS COMING
TOGETHER FOR SUNDAY MASS.
WE'LL TAKE YOU THERE LIVE
NEXT.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] WHERE DO
YOU TURN FOR LEGAL MATTERS?
AT LEGALZOOM, WE'VE CREATED
A BETTER PLACE
TO HANDLE YOUR LEGAL NEEDS.
MAYBE YOU HAVE QUESTIONS
ABOUT INCORPORATING
A BUSINESS
YOU'D LIKE TO START.
OR QUESTIONS
ABOUT PROTECTING YOUR FAMILY
WITH A WILL OR LIVING TRUST.
AND YOU'D LIKE TO FIND
THE RIGHT ATTORNEY
TO HELP GUIDE YOU ALONG,
ANSWER ANY QUESTIONS
AND OFFER ADVICE.
WITH AN "A" RATING FROM
THE BETTER BUSINESS BUREAU
LEGALZOOM HELPS YOU GET
PERSONALIZED AND AFFORDABLE
LEGAL PROTECTION.
IN MOST STATES, A LEGAL PLAN
ATTORNEY IS AVAILABLE WITH
EVERY PERSONALIZED DOCUMENT
TO ANSWER ANY QUESTIONS.
GET STARTED AT LEGALZOOM.COM
TODAY.
AND NOW YOU'RE PROTECTED.
LIKE SAY, GAS STATION SUSHI.
CHEAP IS GOOD.
AND SUSHI, GOOD.
BUT CHEAP SUSHI, NOT SO GOOD.
IT'S LIKE THAT SUPER-LOW RATE
ON NOT ENOUGH CAR INSURANCE.
PRETTY SKETCHY.
♪
AND THEN THERE ARE
THE GOOD DECISIONS.
LIKE ESURANCE.
THEIR COVERAGE COUNSELOR TOOL
HELPS YOU CHOOSE
THE RIGHT COVERAGE FOR YOU
AT A GREAT PRICE.
[ stomach growls ]
WITHOUT FEELING QUEASY.
THAT'S INSURANCE
FOR THE MODERN WORLD.
ESURANCE.
NOW BACKED BY ALLSTATE.
CLICK OR CALL.
>>  WELCOME BACK.
AS THE NATION MOURNS FRIDAY'S
UNTHINKABLE TRAGEDY.
QUIET TOWN OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT IS COMING TOGETHER
FOR SUNDAY MASS TO PRAY FOR
THEIR LOVED ONES.
>> Kelly: AND FOX RADIO IS
LIVE WITH US FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT FROM THE ST. ROSE
OF LIMA CATHOLIC CHURCH TO
PROVIDE US WITH MORE INSIGHTS
INTO THIS HORRIBLE TRAGEDY
THAT'S UNFOLDED AND NOW GRIPS
THE NATION.
TODD, WHAT CAN YOU TELL US?
>> GOOD MORNING, GRAY SKIES,
VERY SOMBER DAY HERE AND FOR
THE PAST HOUR, WE'VE SEEN CAR
AFTER CAR ARRIVING, THE
PARKING LOT IS JUST ABOUT
FILLED UP AS FOLKS GATHER FOR
MORNING WORSHIP.
AS THEY'RE DOING AT CHURCH
HOUSES ACROSS THE NATION,
PEOPLE COMING TOGETHER TO
PRAY, TO LISTEN TO THEIR
PASTORS AND HOPING TO MAKE
SENSE OF THE SENSELESS.
NOW, THIS PARTICULAR CHURCH
HAS BEEN A GATHERING PLACE FOR
THOSE, HERE IN THIS COMMUNITY
TO PRAY, TO EMBRACE ONE
ANOTHER, TO CONSOLE EACH OTHER
AND THEY HAVE SOME DIFFICULT
DAYS AHEAD.
I THINK ONE OF THE MORE
POIGNANT MOMENTS HAPPENED ON
FRIDAY.
THE CHILDREN OF THE CHURCH
HELD THEIR LIVE NATIVITY SCENE
AND SADLY ONE OF THE GIRLS WHO
WAS KILLED IN THE ATTACK ON
THE SCHOOL WAS SUPPOSED TO BE
AN ANGEL IN THAT PRODUCTION.
AND I WANT TO SHARE WITH YOU,
WHAT THE MINISTER OF ST. ROSE
SHARED WITH REUTERS.
HE SAYS OF THIS LITTLE
SIX-YEAR-OLD GIRL.
SHE WAS SUPPOSED TO BE AN
ANGEL IN THE PLAY AND NOW SHE
IS AN ANGEL IN HEAVEN.
GUYS.
>> Dave: YEAH, TODD, ONE OF
THE THINGS WE WERE SURPRISED
BY IS ONE OF THE FATHER--
ONE OF THE VICTIM'S FATHERS
WHO CAME OUT AND SPOKE NOT
ABOUT ANGER TOWARD THE FAMILY
OF THE SHOOTER, BUT FOR
FORGIVENESS, WHICH QUITE
FRANKLY ASTOUNDED ME AS A
PARENT OF YOUNG CHILDREN.
IS THAT THE MESSAGE YOU'RE
HEARING AT THE CHURCH THERE IS
IT ONE OF FORGIVENESS OR WHAT
ARE PEOPLE SAYING?
>> THIS IS SOMETHING AMAZING--
(INAUDIBLE) OH, LOOKS LIKE
WE'RE HAVING SOME SIGNAL
DISRUPTION THERE, WE APOLOGIZE
FOR THAT, WE'VE LOST TODD, HE
WAS GOING TO TALK ABOUT THE
POSSIBILITY OF WHAT
PARISHIONERS THERE MIGHT BE
SAYING THIS MORNING, AS THEY
GO TO CHURCH.
>> Dave: WHAT WOULD YOU SAY,
KELLY?
>> I WOULD HAVE THE SAME -- I
WOULD HAVE THE SAME PHILOSOPHY
OR BELIEF BECAUSE OF MY FAITH
IN GOD, I WOULD HAVE THE SAME
KIND OF REACTION THAT ROBBIE
HAS, IT WOULD BE DIFFICULT TO
EXPRESS THAT, AND PAINFUL, I
MEAN, VICERAL.
YOU AND I HAVE CHILDREN, I
EVEN HAVE GRANDCHILDREN, SOME
OF THOSE GRANDCHILDREN UNDER
THE AGE OF SIX AND IT'S SO
VICERAL AND YET AT THE SAME
TIME YOU HAVE TO HAVE
SOMETHING THAT CAN MAKE SENSE
OF IT ALL.
MAKING SENSE OF THE SENSELESS
AND FINDING HOPE FOR THE
HOPELESS AND TO ME, ONLY GOD
CAN DO THAT, NO LAW IN THE
LAND CAN DO THAT AND NO HE
ANALOGY OF CIRCUMSTANCES CAN
DO THAT, BUT MY FAITH IS MY
ROCK AND MY BED ROCK AND WE
TALK ABOUT AMAZING GRACE.
THAT'S WHAT ROBBIE PARKER HAS
DISPLAYED IN THIS, LOSING HIS
OLDEST DAUGHTER, HIS LOVE.
>> Dave: YEAH.
>> Kelly: AND THEN MOVING
FORWARD TO SAY THAT I FORGIVE,
AND FROM THAT FORGIVENESS, HE
WILL FIND NOT ONLY
RECONCILIATION, BUT ALSO
RESTORATION AND HEALING, IT
WILL NEVER BE THE SAME, NEVER
BE THE SAME, BUT THERE WILL BE
HEALING.
>> Dave: WELL SAID.
TODD WILL JOIN US LATER ON IN
THE PROGRAM FROM NEWTOWN,
AHEAD IN THE SHOW.
FROM THE DEPTHS OF TRAGEDY,
HEROES ARE EMERGING.
ONE TEACHER HID HER STUDENTS
AND ENDED UP LOSING HER OWN
LIFE.
HER INCREDIBLE STORY COMING
UP.
.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S SIMPLE PHYSICS...
A BODY AT REST
TENDS TO STAY AT REST...
WHILE A BODY IN MOTION
TENDS TO STAY IN MOTION.
STAYING ACTIVE CAN ACTUALLY
EASE ARTHRITIS SYMPTO.
BUT IF YOU HAVE ARTHRITIS,
STAYING ACTIVE
CAN BE DIFFICULT.
PRESCRIPTION CELEBREX
CAN HELP RELIEVE ARTHRITIS PAIN
SO YOUR BODY
CAN STAY IN MOTION.
BECAUSE JUST ONE
200MG CELEBREX A DAY
CAN PROVIDE 24 HOUR RELIEF
FOR MANY WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND INFLAMMATION.
PLUS, IN CLINICAL STUDIES,
CELEBREX IS PROVEN TO IMPROVE
DAILY PHYSICAL FUNCTION
SO MOVING IS EASIER.
CELEBREX CAN BE TAKEN WITH
OR WITHOUT FOOD.
AND IT'S NOT A NARCOTIC.
YOU AND YOUR DOCTOR
SHOULD BALANCE THE BENETS
WITH THEISKS.
ALL PRESCRIPTION NSAIDS,
LIKE CELEBREX, IBUPROFEN,
NAPROXEN, AND MELOXICAM
HAVE THE SAME
CARDIOVASCULAR WARNING.
THEY ALL MAY INCREASE
THE CHANCE
OF HEART ATTACK OR STROKE,
WHICH CAN LEAD TO DEATH.
THIS CHANCE INCREASES
IF YOU HAVE HEART DISEASE
RISK FACTORS
SUH AS HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE
OR WHEN NSAIDS ARE TAKEN
FOR LONG PERIODS.
NSAIDS, INCLUDING CELEBREX,
INCREASE THE CHANCE OF SERIOUS
SKIN OR ALLERGIC REACTIONS
OR STOMACH A INTESTINE
PROBLEMS,
SUCH AS BLEEDING AND CERS,
WHICH CAN OCCUR WITHOUT WARNING
AND MAY CAUSE DEATH.
PATIENTS ALSO TAKING ASPIRIN
AND THE ELDEY
ARE AT INCRSED RISK FOR
STOCH BLEEDING AND ULCERS.
DO NOT TAKE CELEBREX IF YOU'VE
HAD AN ASTHMA ATTACK, HIVES,
OR OTHER ALLERGIES TO ASPIRIN,
NSAIDS OR SULFONAMIDES.
GET HELP RIGHTWAY IF YOU HAVE
SWELNG OF THE FACE OR THROAT,
OR TROUBLE BREATHING.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
YOUR MEDICAL HISTORY
AND FIND AN ARTHRITIS TREATMENT
FOR YOU.
VISIT CELEBREX.COM AND ASK
YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT CELEBREX.
FOR A BODY IN MOTION.
>>  THEY WERE TERRIFIED.
THEY WERE TERRIFIED AND THEY
HAD JUST WITNESSED SOMETHING
AND THEY WERE, THEY WERE
TERRIFIED.
>> IT'S MOST FRIGHTENING THING
I'VE EVER BEEN THROUGH.
>> YOU HAVE NO WORDS, SHEER
TERROR.
>> IT DOESN'T EVEN SEEM REAL,
IT JUST NOT SEEM LIKE IT'S
EVEN POSSIBLE.
>> AND I KEPT HEARING THESE
BOOMING NOISES.
>> THE CHILDREN OBVIOUSLY WERE
VERY SHAKEN, THEY WERE CRYING
IN THE CLOSET.
WHEN THEY WERE LEAVING THE
POLICE TOLD THEM TO HOLD HANDS
AND CLOSE THEIR EYES.
>> AND THEY HAVE THEIR ENTIRE
LIVES AHEAD OF THEM.
AND FIRST DATES, GRADUATIONS.GR.
>>  EXTREMELY EMOTIONAL, BUT
WE THANK YOU FOR JOINING US
TODAY, 48 HOURS BEYOND THE
TRAGEDY UNFOLDED IN NEWTOWN
AND WE ARE STILL -- I HAVE TO
BE HONEST HERE, ALL THREE OF
US ARE PARENTS AND SO WE GO
THROUGH THE SAME THINGS THAT
OTHER PEOPLE ARE GOING
THROUGH, SITTING AT HOME,
PERHAPS, YOU KNOW, SAYING, MY
GOD, WHAT'S NEXT?
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
AND WE LOVE OUR CHILDREN AND
WE ARE ALWAYS PROUD PARENTS
AND WE OUR HEARTS GO OUT.
SO FROM ALL OF US AT FOX NEWS
I'VE GOT TO SAY OUR PRAYER,
CONDOLENCES AND SUPPORT GO OUT
TO THE PEOPLE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> Alisyn: ONE.
THINGS WE CLING TO DURING THAT
OBVIOUSLY INCREDIBLY GRIEF
STRICKEN TIME
HARROWING STORIES OF PEOPLE
WHO BRAVED THE THE DANGER AND
SHELTERED THE KIDS AND ONE OF
THEM IS 27-YEAR-OLD TEACHER
VICTORIA SOTO.
AND THERE ARE VAGUE DETAILS
BECAUSE A LOT HAS BEEN
REPORTED BY HER SIX AND
SEVEN-YEAR-OLD STUDENT AND
IT'S NOT CLEAR WHAT SHE DID,
BUT SHE SHIELDED THEM.
ONE SHE QUICKLY PUT THEM INTO
A CLOSET AND CONFRONTED THEM
AND THE GUNMAN ASKED HER, AND
SHE SAID I SENT THEM TO THE
GYM.
AND LIED TO THEM.
AND THERE ARE REPORTS THAT HE
STARTED FIRING AND SHIELDED
THEM WITH HER BODY AND SHE
DIED AND THEY SURVIVED.
>> NOT JUST THAT, BUT TO THINK
OF THE TEACHERS THAT TEACH AT
THAT SCHOOL, YOUR SCHOOL, AND
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY AND A
GOOD TIME WHAT THEY DO FOR
YOUR KIDS NOT JUST TEACHING
THEM, BUT CARING AND
PROTECTING THEM THE BEST THEY
CAN.
ONE OF THE PHOTOS IS THE
SISTER OF THIS 27-YEAR-OLD
TEACHER, THAT'S GILLIAN SOTO,
THERE, OBVIOUSLY, UPON HEARING
THE NEWS OF HER SISTER, SOME
OF THOSE IN THE COMMUNITY
TALKED ABOUT THEIR WONDERFUL
27-YEAR-OLD TEACHER AND HERE
IS WHAT THEY SAID.
>> I DIDN'T KNOW HER AT ALL,
BUT I'M A MOM AND IT COULD
HAVE BEEN MY KID AND WHAT SHE
DID A VERY VERY--
THE PAIN, HOW THOSE MOTHERS
MUST BE FEELING AT THIS TIME
BECAUSE THIS IS MY ONLY CHILD,
BUT I COULDN'T PICTURE THAT,
THAT'S WHY I'M HERE TODAY
BECAUSE SHE SAVED A LOT OF
KIDS LIVES.
>> I JUST FEEL SAD THAT SHE'S
IN A THE BETTER PLACE.
>> AND ONE OF THE THEMES THAT
HAS COME UP OVER AND OVER
AGAIN IN THE PAST 48 HOURS
THAT WE HAVE BEEN TALKING
ABOUT THIS, AS EVERYBODY TRIES
TO FIGURE OUT WHAT CAN WE EVER
DO TO PREVENT SOMETHING LIKE
THIS FROM HAPPENING AGAIN, HOW
CAN WE EKE OUT SOME MESSAGE
HERE SO THAT EVERYBODY ELSE IS
SPARED GRIEF AND THE COMMON
THEME, IT HASN'T, QUITE
FRANKLY, BEEN ABOUT GUN
CONTROL, IT'S BEEN ABOUT THE
MENTAL HEALTH INDUSTRY AND
THAT SOMETHING HAS GONE WRONG
WITH THESE MENTAL HEALTH IN
THIS COUNTRY, PARTICULARLY OF
TROUBLED YOUNG MEN WHO THEN
SOMEHOW GAIN ACCESS TO
WEAPONS, FOR THE LIONS SHARE
OF SCHOOL SHOOTINGS HAS BEEN
CARRIED OUT BY TEENAGE OR
YOUNG MEN AND DR. KEITH ABLOW
SPOKE IN SUCH A COMPELLING AND
COMPREHENSIVE WAY ABOUT ALL OF
THIS.
>> WE'LL ALSO SEE EVIDENCE OF
A MENTAL HEALTH CARE SYSTEM IN
UTTER DISARRAY HERE, BECAUSE
THAT'S WHAT OUR MENTAL HEALTH
CARE SYSTEM IS, COMPLETELY
UNRELIABLE, UNDERSTAFFED, TOO
LITTLE EXPERTISE, AND NOT
KNOWING WHICH WAY TO TURN WITH
SOMEONE LIKE THIS.
>> THE MENTAL HEALTH CARE
SYSTEM IN AMERICA, WE HAVE
PUSHED DOWN TO THE LOWEST
LEVELS, THE EXPERTISE THAT
SHOULD BE AT THE HIGHEST
LEVEL, WE HAVE KIDS LIKE THIS,
AND WORSE.
WHO ARE ALREADY EXPRESSING
VIOLENT FANTASIES, BEING
TREATED BY NEWLY MINTED SOCIAL
WORKERS WHO HAVE NEVER BEEN
SCHOOLED IN INTROSPECTIVE
TECHNIQUES, WHO DON'T DEAL
WITH VIOLENCE ON A DAY-TO-DAY
BASIS.
WE HAVE NO FORENSIC TRAINING
WHY, BECAUSE INSURANCE
COMPANIES PAY ONLY THEM.
WE HAVE INSURANCE COMPANIES
WON'T PAY PSYCHIATRIST TO DO
THAT WORK.
WE HAVE NO CONNECTION BETWEEN
OUR CRISIS TEAMS AND COMMUNITY
MENTAL HEALTH CENTERS AND THE
POLICE, OUR JUDICIARY AND OUR
HOSPITALS.
WE HAVE PEOPLE IN E.R. WHO ARE
PSYCHIATRY RESIDENTS AND
PSYCHIATRISTS WHO DON'T
LITESERLY KNOW WHO TO CALL IF
THEY HAVE A PSYCHIATRIC
PATIENT COME INTO THE E.R.,
WHO'S EXPRESSING VIOLENT IDEAS
SHORT OF MURDER OR FOR WHOM
THEY'RE TERRIBLY CONCERNED.
WE STILL HAVE ALL KINDS OF
EXPERTS, QUOTE, UNQUOTE,
PSYCHIATRISTS, SOCIAL WORKERS,
AND OTHERS, WHO BELIEVE THAT
IF SOMEBODY SAYS I WON'T DO
IT, WHEN THEY GET TO THE E.R.
AFTER THEY SIT SAID IN A
PSYCHIATRIST'S OFFICE I DO
INTEND TO HARM PEOPLE BECAUSE
THEY'RE QUOTE, UNQUOTE,
CONTRACTED TO SAFETY AND
INSURANCE COMPANY WON'T PAY
FOR THEM TO BE IN THE THE
HOSPITAL.
RIGHT NOW WE DON'T HAVE A
MENTAL HEALTH CARE SYSTEM.
WE HAVE A VARIETY OF
CLINICIANS, POORLY TRAINED,
NOT IN ANY WAY INTEGRATED,
WITH NO MARCHING ORDERS AS TO
WHAT TO DO WITH THE
POTENTIALLY VIOLENTLY MENTALLY
ILL.
>> Dave: YOU DON'T WANT TO
POLITICIZE THIS, BUT IT'S HARD
TO IMAGINE THAT SYSTEM GETTING
ANY BETTER IN THE WAKE OF OUR
RENEWED HEALTH CARE SYSTEM,
HOW THE HEALTH CARE SYSTEM IN
THIS COUNTRY HAS BEEN MADE
OVER.
IT'S HARD TO IMAGINE IT
GETTING BETTER ON THAT FRONT
OVER THE THE NEXT COUPLE OF
YEARS.
>> Kelly: TO THIS POINT
THOUGH, THERE ARE SOME STATES
THAT ARE BEING MORE PROACTIVE
NOW, BECAUSE THEY REALIZE
THERE ARE ISSUES OUT THERE AND
WHEN THEY HEAR OF SOMETHING,
OR THERE'S A THREAT BEING
MADE.
MAYBE SOME PARANOID
SCHIZOPHRENIA BEHAVIOR.
THEY WILL, THOSE EMERGENCY
CLINICIANS WILL MAKE CALLS TO
PEOPLE WHO ARE GUARDIANS AND
STATE AUTHORITIES AND SAY WE
THINK THERE MIGHT BE A PROBLEM
AND CHECK THIS GUY OUT.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED IN
THIS PARTICULAR SITUATION, BUT
WE DO KNOW PERHAPS THERE WERE
ISSUES GOING ON AND PEOPLE
TALKING ABOUT ADAM LANZA AS
BEING A LONER, SOMEONE WHO
EVEN WENT THROUGH HIGH SCHOOL
VERY MUCH ALONE, VERY SMART,
BRILLIANT, BUT YET, VISIBLY
DISTURBED.
SO WE DON'T KNOW.
WE KNOW THAT HE GAINED ACCESS
TO THE GUNS THROUGH HIS
MOTHER, NANCY LANZA, WHO WAS A
GUN COLLECTOR.
SO, WE HAVE TO FIND OUT ALL
THE DETAILS.
POLICE ARE STILL
INVESTIGATING, PUTTING THE
PIECESES TOGETHER, BUT I THINK
IT'S VERY KEY AND TELLING WHAT
DR. KEITH ABLOW TALKED ABOUT
AND THEN ON THE FIELDS OF
THAT, WE INTERVIEWED A FRIEND
OF THE PRINCIPAL OF SANDY HOOK
WHO GAVE HER LIFE IN
PROTECTION OF HER CHILDREN AND
HE WENT TON SAY THAT THERE'S
MENTAL ISSUE PROBLEM.
WHEN HE WE ASKED HIM HOW DOES
THE COMMUNITY GO FORWARD.
WE'VE GOT TO PRAY FOR THE
FAMILIES, BUT DEAL WITH THIS
ISSUE.
>> Alisyn: EVERYONE HAS
TOUCHED ON THAT.
ALMOST EVERY GUEST, REGARDLESS
OF THEIR FIELD, HOW WE HAVE A
MENTAL HEALTH PROBLEM AND SAID
IF YOU KNOW A TEENAGER THAT'S
FEELING ALIENATED REACH OUT TO
THEM.
>> Dave: DO SOMETHING, TELL
SOMEONE.
>> Alisyn: IN THE MEANTIME.
WE HAVE A LOT MORE INFORMATION
FOR YOU.
THE SEARCH FOR A MOTIVE, THE
POLICE SAY THEY HAVE VERY GOOD
EVIDENCE.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
WHAT IS THEIR EVIDENCE?
WE'LL TRY TO GET THAT FOR YOU
NEXT.
♪
Before taking TAMIFLU tell your
doctor if you're pregnant,
nursing. have serious
health conditions,
or take other medicines.
If you develop an allergic
reaction, a severe rash,
or signs of unusual behavior,
stop taking TAMIFLU and call
your doctor immediately.
Children and adolescents in
particular may be at an
increased risk
of seizures, confusion
or abnormal behavior.
The most common
side effects are
mild to moderate nausea
and vomiting.
The flu comes on fast,
so ask your
doctor about TAMIFLU.
Prescription for flu.
>>  AS THE INVESTIGATION INTO
FRIDAY'S HORRIFIC EVENTS
CONTINUE, AUTHORITIES SAY
THEY'VE FOUND, QUOTE, VERY
GOOD EVIDENCE ON THE SHOOTER.
BUT WHAT EXACTLY IS GOOD
EVIDENCE.
LET'S ASK FORMER HOMICIDE
DETECTIVE ROD WHEELER, GOOD TO
SEE YOU, SIR.
>> GOOD MORNING, DAVE.
>> Dave: WHAT MIGHT THAT
EVIDENCE BE?
>> I CAN TELL YOU EXACTLY WHAT
I THINK IT IS.
LET ME TAKE YOU BACK A LITTLE
BIT.
YOU KNOW, I THINK THE SCHOOL
SYSTEM, DAVE, WAS VERY
FAMILIAR WITH LANZA, AND LET
ME TELL YOU WHY.
I ALSO THINK THE POLICE
DEPARTMENT IN THAT COMMUNITY
WAS FAMILIAR WITH LANZA.
LOOK, THIS WHOLE SITUATION
STARTED MONTHS AGO, IT JUST
DIDN'T HAPPEN THAT FRIDAY
MORNING.
I BELIEVE, AND THIS IS ALL
SPECULATION, I'M NOT OBVIOUSLY
INVOLVED IN THE INVESTIGATION,
BUT I BELIEVE LANZA HAD MADE
PREVIOUS THREATS TO THAT
SCHOOL AS OF RECENT.
AND WHY DO I BELIEVE THAT?
BECAUSE AS YOU KNOW ALL THE
REPORTS STATED THAT THE SCHOOL
RECENTLY HAD AN ELABORATE
SECURITY SYSTEM INSTALLED.
WHY DID THEY HAVE TO SYSTEM
STALLED?
THAT SYSTEM IS UNUSUAL FOR THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE REASON I BELIEVE THEY DID,
LANZA HAD MADE SOME THREATS.
WHY DID HE SHOOT HIS MOTHER.
HERE IS WHY I BELIEVE HE
KILLED HIS MOTHER FRIDAY
MORNING, A FAMILY MEMBER,
DAVE, HAS TO HAVE ANOTHER
FAMILY MEMBER PROBATED IF
THEY'RE SHOWING SIGNS OF
MENTAL ILLNESS.
IN ORDER TO HAVE THEM PROBATED
BY THE COURT YOU HAVE TO PUT
TOGETHER COLLECTION OF
EVIDENCE, INFORMATION, THAT'S
GOOD EVIDENCE THAT THE POLICE
DEPARTMENT, THE POLICE CHIEF
WAS TALKING ABOUT YESTERDAY
WHEN HE SAID WE HAVE GOOD
EVIDENCE.
WHAT HE WAS TALKING ABOUT IS
THAT THE MOTHER WAS PROBABLY
STARTING TO PUT ALL THIS HAVE
STUFF TOGETHER.
LANZA CAME IN, LANZA WAS
UPSET.
HE COULDN'T BELIEVE THAT HIS
MOTHER WOULD DO THIS TO HIM.
AND SO, THAT'S WHY HE KILLED
HER, AND THEN HE WENT TO THE
SCHOOL.
NOW, WHEN HE GOT TO THE
SCHOOL, DAVE, HE COULDN'T GET
IN, YOU KNOW WHY?
THEY HAD THAT ELABORATE
SECURITY SYSTEM THEY DID NOT
HAVE THE SYSTEM WHEN HE FIRST
WENT TO THE SCHOOL.
AND I THINK IT STARTED MONTHS
AGO, I DON'T THINK IT JUST
STARTED THIS PAST WEEK.
>> Dave: AND JUST TO BE CLEAR
WE HAVE NO WORD CONFIRMING ANY
THREATS TO THE POLICE, THE
SCHOOL.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> Dave: I LIVE ABOUT 40
MINUTES AWAY.
MY CHILDREN'S ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL HAS A SIMILAR SECURITY
SYSTEM AND THAT'S NOT AT ALL
BASED ON THREATS, EXPLAIN WHAT
YOU MEAN BY THE PROCESS OF
BEING PROBATED AND WHAT THAT
EXACTLY WOULD MEAN FOR A
20-YEAR-OLD AND THE MOTHER?
>> WELL, ANYTIME A FAMILY
MEMBER, DAVE, IS SHOWING SIGNS
OF HOSTILITY OF BEING VIOLENT
AND YOU WANT TO TRY TO GET
THAT PERSON TO THEIR
PSYCHOLOGIST OR MAKE SURE THAT
THEY TAKE MEDICATION, YOU HAVE
TO PRESENT EVIDENCE TO THE
COURT.
EVIDENCE COULD BE A LETTER
FROM THE SCHOOL, IF THIS GUY
HAD MADE THREATS TO THE SCHOOL
IN THE PAST, AND ALL KINDS OF
THINGS AND IN ORDER TO DO THAT
YOU HAVE TO PRESENT THAT TO A
JUDGE AND THEN THE JUDGE WILL
SEND IT OVER TO THE POLICE
DEPARTMENT AND THE POLICE
DEPARTMENT WILL GO OUT AND
THEN THIS'LL ARREST THIS
PERSON AND TAKE THEM TO A
HOSPITAL.
NOW, GOING BACK TO THE
SECURITY SYSTEM.
YOU'RE CORRECT, ALL SCHOOLS
ARE LOCKED DOWN NOW, AND ALL
SCHOOLS HAVE SOME DEGREE OF
SECURITY, BUT FROM WHAT IT
SOUNDS LIKE, THIS SCHOOL HAD A
DIFFERENT SYSTEM, A VERY
ELABORATE SYSTEM AND THEY
HAVEN'T SAID EXACTLY WHAT IT
WAS, BUT I DO BELIEVE, DAVE,
THAT IT WAS THE RESULT OF AN
EXPERIENCE WITH THIS GUY,
LANZA IN THE PAST.
LANZA WAS NOT A PERSON THAT
THEY WERE UNFAMILIAR WITH, AND
WHEN I SAY THEY, I'M TALKING
THE POLICE DEPARTMENT, AND
THINK THE PRINCIPAL.
>> Dave: WHAT SHOULD LOCAL
POLICE DEPARTMENTS BE DOING
ACROSS THE COUNTRY IF THEY GET
WORD OF DISTURBING BEHAVIOR,
OF YOUNG INDIVIDUALS LIKE THIS
20-YEAR-OLD?
>> WELL, HERE IS THE REALITY,
DAVE, AND I'VE BEEN ON A LOT
OF CASES LIKE THIS, WHERE WE
HAVE INDIVIDUALS.
LOOK, A FAMILY MEMBER WILL
CALL THE POLICE BECAUSE
THEY'LL SAY THEIR FAMILY
MEMBER IS--
THEIR RELATIVE IS BECOMING
VIOLENT AND BELIEVE IT OR NOT,
DAVE, IT'S NOTHING THE POLICE
CAN DO AT THAT TIME UNLESS THE
POLICE SEE ACTUAL EVIDENCE AT
THAT TIME OF SOMEBODY BEING
DESTRUCTIVE, WE CAN'T TAKE ANY
ACTION AT ALL.
WE HAVE TO ADVISE THE FAMILY
MEMBER, YOU HAVE TO GO TO THE
COURT, TAKE EVIDENCE AND THEN
THE COURT WILL TELL US TO COME
BACK OUT AND GET THIS PERSON.
EVERY POLICE DEPARTMENT, DAVE,
IN THE UNITED STATES OPERATES
THE SAME WAY.
YOU HAVE TO DO IT BY WAY OF
THE COURT.
WE CANNOT JUST TAKE ACTION,
DAVE, AGAIN, UNLESS WE
SPECIFICALLY SEE THAT PERSON
BEING VIOLENT AT THAT TIME.
>> Dave: AND WE CAN SAY THE
POLICE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
ACTED VERY QUICKLY.
THEY WERE ON THE SITE WITHIN
MINUTES OF THE FIRST 911 CALL.
ROD WHEELER, FORMER HOMICIDE
DETECTIVE, WE APPRECIATE YOU
BEING WITH US.
>> THANK YOU, DAVE.
>> Dave: UP NEXT, WHAT PUSHED
THIS 20-YEAR-OLD TO KILL?
IS THERE EVEN AN ANSWER OR
SOME PEOPLE JUST PLAIN
INNATELY EVIL?
THAT'S NEXT.
♪
THIS IS AMERICA.
WE DON'T LET FREQUENT HEARTBURN
COME BETWEEN US
AND WHAT WE LOVE.
SO IF YOU'RE ONE OF THEM PEOPLE
WHO GETS HEARTBURN
AND THEN TREATS DAY AFR DAY...
BLOCK THE ACID WITH PRILOSEC OTC
AND DON'T GET HEARTBURN
IN THE FIRST PLACE!
[ Male Announcer ]
E PILL EACHMORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBUR
Neural speeds
increasing to 4G LTE.
Brain upgrading to a quad-core
processor.
Predictive intelligence
with Google Now complete.
Introducing DROID DNA by HTC.
It's not an upgrade
to your phone.
It's an upgrade to yourself.
♪
>>  WILL WE EVER GET AN ANSWER
TO WHAT CAUSED THIS SHOOTER TO
MASSACRE CHILDREN?
IS THERE AN ANSWER OR ARE SOME
PEOPLE PLAIN EVIL?
>> A CLINICAL PSYCHIATRIST AT
COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY AND THE
AUTHOR OF "THE ANATOMY OF
EVIL", DR. MICHAEL H STONE IS
HERE TO EXPLAIN.
AND YOU'VE WRITTEN THIS BOOK
"ANATOMY OF EVIL" AND WE'VE
SEEN IT SHOTTER OF PIECE OF
NEWTOWN.
>> IT DID.
>> HOW AND WHY?
>> WHAT HAPPENED WAS HEART
BREAKING, SHOCKING, HORRENDOUS
BEYOND ANYONE'S ABILITY TO
ENCOMPASS THAT AND SO IT'S AN
EMOTION THAT STIRS UP IN US
WHEN WE SEE SOMETHING AS
HORRIFYING AS WHAT HAPPENED IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THAT, AND WHEN SOMEONE SAYS
WHAT HAPPENS, THAT WAS AN EVIL
ACT.
THAT WAS AN EVIL, TERRIBLE
THING.
IT'S WHAT PEOPLE IN THE STREET
SAY, WHAT JUDGES SAY, WHAT
PROSECUTORS SAY, WHAT
JOURNALISTS SAY.
>> Kelly: EVEN THE GOVERNOR OF
THE STATE OF CONNECTICUT.
>> YES, IT'S A WORD THAT WE
USE INVARIABLY FOR THIS KIND
OF SITUATION.
WHEN LITTLE INNOCENT CHILDREN
ARE MOWED DOWN, YOU KNOW, BY A
MASS MURDERER.
>> Alisyn: AND DR., WE SHOULD
LET OUR VIEWERS KNOW YOU HAVE
STUDIED 208 CASES OF MASS
MURDER, AND SPEAK MORE TO
THIS, NOT ALL MASSACRE OF
CHILDREN, BUT SIMILAR TO THIS,
BUT I'M SURPRISED YOU'RE
CALLING SOMETHING EVIL,
BECAUSE I WOULD THINK THAT THE
CLINICAL MENTAL HEALTH FIELD
THAT YOU ARE IN WOULD SAY THAT
THIS IS MENTAL ILLNESS, THIS
ISN'T EVIL.
>> THIS PARTICULAR FELLOW, I
THINK, HAD A PSYCHIATRIC
CONDITION.
I THINK ASPERGER'S WAS A GOOD
NAME FOR IT.
HE'S SOMEBODY WHO WAS BORN
GENETICALLY, INCAPABLE OF
FORMING CLOSE RELATIONSHIPS
WITH PEOPLE, INCAPABLE OF
MAKING EYE CONTACT, INCAPABLE
OF SOCIAL RECIPROCITY AND ALL
THE SCIENCE THAT WE SEE IN THE
BOOK, AND AS A RESULT, THEY'RE
ODD, THEY'RE MARGINALIZED
THEY'RE PECULIAR, THEY CAN'T
MAKE FRIENDS.
SO AS TIME GOES ON AND YOU GET
TOWARDS 18, 19, 20 WHEN YOU'RE
EXPECTED TO HAVE GIRLFRIENDS
AND INTIMATE RELATIONSHIPS,
AND CLOSE BUDDIES AND SO ON
AND YOU CAN'T BECAUSE THERE'S
SOMETHING WEIRD ABOUT YOU, YOU
TEND RATHER THAN TO SAY, OH, I
GUESS YOU'LL SORT OF AN ODD
LONER, I GUESS I JUST HAVE TO
ACCEPT MY LOT AND GET ON THE
INTERNET AND PLAY GAMES.
NO, YOU BLAME SOMEBODY.
AND THE FAMILY SAYS SHE'S A
DEDICATED MOM AND SHE
SACRIFICED A LOT, INCLUDING, A
CAREER, AND TO GIVE TO HER SON
SHE THEN HOME SCHOOLED.
WHAT MAKES YOU THINK--
>> I THINK SHE WAS PROBABLY
MORE THAN CONNECTED ENOUGH,
BUT AS HE WOULD EXPERIENCE IT,
SHE MAY NOT AT ALL HAVE BEEN
CONNECTED ENOUGH, IN OTHER
WORDS, IS HE SUPPOSING YOU'RE
BORN WITH A PECULIARITY, YOU
NEED TO BE HANDCUFFED TO YOUR
MOM SO SHE'S THERE ENOUGH.
WHICH IS MORE THAN ANY MOTHER
COULD BE OR CAN BE.
AND LET'S SAY HE GETS 90% OF
THE ATTENTION AND SHE GIVES
50%, WHICH IS MORE THAN MOST
KIDS NEED OR EVER GET.
IN HIS MIND SHE'S SHORT
CHANGING HIM.
SO I SUSPECT THAT SHE GAVE,
PROBABLY DOUBLE THE ATTENTION
THAT SHE DID TO RYAN, THE
BROTHER, OR AN AVERAGE MOTHER
WOULD GIVE TO A DISTURBED KID
OF THIS SORT, BUT IN HIS MIND,
IT COULD BE VERY DIFFERENT,
HOW HE EXPERIENCED IT AND
THAT'S OF COURSE THE
DETERMINING FACTOR.
>> Kelly: WHERE DO YOU SEE
EVIL IN THIS CASE?
BECAUSE THERE ARE SKEPTICS WHO
WOULD TRY TO DISPROVE YOU,
SAYING THAT EVIL DOES NOT
EXIST, THEY'RE BORN UNDER
CONDITIONS AND THEY HAVE TO
DEAL WITH INNATE CONDITIONS.
BUT WHERE DO YOU FIND THE
PROOF THAT EVIL DOES EXIST?
>> EVIL IS NOT SOMETHING THAT
COMES IN THE SKY AND LANDS ON
YOU, CERTAIN PEOPLE, LIKE A
BLACK CLOUD THAT DISSENDS ON
YOU.
THAT'S THE WRONG WAY TO THINK
ABOUT IT.
YOU THINK ABOUT THE EVIL AS
THE WORD SIGNIFYING AS
EMOTIONS AND ALL OF THE
EXPERIENCE WHEN WE'RE
CONFRONTED WITH SOMETHING THAT
IS HORRIFYING.
>> Kelly: AND GO INTO A DARK
PLACE THEN.
>> YES, AND SOME PEOPLE ARE
BORN, A SMALL NUMBER OF
PEOPLE, KNOCK ON WOOD, ARE
BORN WITH A PREDISPOSITION TO
DO THE SORT OF THING IF THEY
HAVE VERY LITTLE CAPACITY FOR
EMPATHY, IN OTHER WORDS, FOR
THE FEELINGS AND CARING ABOUT
THE FEELINGS OF OTHER PEOPLE.
PSYCHOPATH, WE USE THE TERM
PSYCHOPATH
PSYCHOPATH TO CHARACTERIZE
PEOPLE WHO ARE CALLUS,
INCAPABLE OF REMORSE OR GUILT.
HAVE NO EMPATHY AND DON'T CARE
ABOUT THE FETALS FEELINGS OF
OTHERS.
I DON'T THINK THAT ADAM LANZA
WAS A PSYCHOPATH.
HE HAS THE SAME CAPACITY FOR
EMPATHY.
A PERSON LIKE THAT, EITHER
TYPE CAN MOW DOWN A GROUP OF
CHILDREN AS THOUGH WERE YOU
SHOOTING TIN CANS ON THE
FENCE.
>> Alisyn: DOCTOR, IT'S GREAT
TO HAVE YOUR EXPERTISE WITH
US.
THANKS SO MUCH FOR COMING IN,
A PLEASURE.
>> Kelly: WHEN WE COME BACK,
BRAND NEW INFORMATION ON WHERE
THE INVESTIGATION IS HEADED
TODAY, AND WE'LL BE LIVE FROM
N
NEW
>>  GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE,
IT'S SUNDAY, DECEMBER 16TH.
I'M ALISYN CAMEROTA.
THANKS FOR JOINING US THIS
MORNING.
WHAT'S HAPPENING AT THIS HOUR,
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS HEADED TO
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT TO SPEAK
TO RESIDENTS OF SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL.
AND WE'RE LEARNING WHAT
HAPPENED, ABOUT THE VICTIMS OF
THIS HORRIFIC MASSACRE AND
WE'LL HAVE A LIVE REPORT IN
MOMENTS.
>> Dave: MORE QUESTIONS REMAIN
THIS MORNING ABOUT WHY THIS
HAPPENED.
WERE WARNING SIGNS MISSED
ABOUT THE SHOOTER?
WE'LL HAVE THE LATEST ON THE
INVESTIGATION COMING UP.
>> Kelly: AND THE HEROES OF
THIS MASSACRE ARE COMING TO
LIGHT.
PRINCIPALS AND TEACHERS, WHO
DID ALL THEY COULD TO PROTECT
STUDENTS FROM THE GUNMAN, MORE
ON THEIR BRAVERY STRAIGHT
AHEAD.
>>  GOOD MORNING EVEN
EVERYONE, WE APPRECIATE YOU
BEING HERE.
AND APPRECIATE KELLY WRIGHT
FILLING IN FOR CLAYTON, HEART
BREAKING AROUND THE COUNTRY.
WE HAVE NEW INFORMATION WE
WANT TO SHARE WITH YOU AND
BRING TO YOU BECAUSE WE KNOW
SO MANY PEOPLE WANT TO KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED, HOW IT COULD
HAPPEN AND HOW WE COULD
PREVENT IT IN THE FUTURE.
>> Dave: YEAH, A LOT OF
QUESTIONS ABOUT THE MENTAL
HEALTH CARE SYSTEM IN THIS
COUNTRY, HOW IT NEEDS TO
CHANGE WITH THE NEW
INFORMATION COMING OUT ON
SATURDAY WITH THE NAMES OF THE
VICTIMS WERE RELEASED.
WE NOW KNOW THERE WERE 12
GIRLS, EIGHT BOYS AMONG THEM,
20 CHILDREN KILLED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT ON FRIDAY, ALL OF
THEM AGES SIX AND SEVEN YEARS
OLD.
>> Alisyn: THAT PART WAS SO
HEART WRENCHING TO READ EVEN
JUST WORDS ON A PIECE OF
PAPER, NAMES ON A PIECE OF
PAPER.
YOU'LL REMEMBER THE FIRST
INFORMATION, EVEN PRESIDENT
OBAMA HAD THE INFORMATION THAT
THE VICTIMS WERE BETWEEN FIVE
AND TEN YEARS OLD.
AND NOW WE KNOW THEY WERE ALL
SIX AND SEVEN YEARS OLD, ALL
JUST PART OF, I BELIEVE, TWO
DIFFERENT FIRST GRADE CLASSES.
>> Kelly: AND WE MUST NOT
FORGET THE TEACHERS WHO WERE
ALSO KILLED IN THIS TRAGEDY
AND THE HEROISM AND THE
STORIES OF HOW THEY ACTUALLY,
ONE TEACHER ACTUALLY VEALSHIELDG
THE STUDENTS AND ONE REPORT
SHE SHIELDED STUDENTS FROM
GUNFIRE AND MAYBE HID THEM IN
A CUPBOARD AND CONFRONTED BY
THE SHOOTER AND SAID THEY'RE
ALL IN THE GYM.
AND THE GUNMAN'S FATHER ALSO
COMMENTING ON THE STORY.
>> Dave: WE'RE ALSO LEARNING
MORE ABOUT THE GUNMAN'S FAMILY
AND THE MOTHER DID HAVE ALL OF
THESE WEAPONS LEGALLY
REGISTERED AND ALL THE GUNS
USED IN THE SHOOTING AT LEAST
ACCORDING TO ONE REPORT WERE
REGISTERED TO THE SHOOT'S
MOTHER.
AND WAS PULLED OUT OF THE HIGH
SCHOOL AND HOME SCHOOLED AND
WE KNOW HE STRUGGLED WITH THE
SCHOOL SYSTEM AND WE DON'T
KNOW WHY, A BATTLE BACK AND
FORTH BETWEEN THE SCHOOL
SYSTEM AND THE PARENTS OF THE
SHOOTER, WE DON'T KNOW WHY
YET.
>> Alisyn: THE FATHER OF THE
SHOOTER, HIS NAME IS PETER PUT
OUT A STATEMENT IN WHICH HE
SAID OUR HEARTS GO OUT TO THE
FAMILY AND FRIENDS WHO LOST
LOVED ONES AND TO ALL OF THOSE
INJURED AND ARE FAMILIES
BRIEFI
GRIEVING ALONG WITH THOSE WHO
WERE INJURED, OUR FAMILY IS
GRIEVING ALONG WITH ALL THOSE
WHO HAVE BEEN AFFECT BY THIS
ENORMOUS TRAGEDY AND TRYING TO
FIND ANSWERS THAT WE CAN.
>> Dave: THEY HAD BEEN
DIVORCED FOR A COUPLE OF YEARS
NOW AND THE MOTHER REPORTEDLY
STRUGGLED MIGHTILY WITH THAT
DIVORCE, BUT SHE WAS THE ONE
RAISING THIS 20-YEAR-OLD THERE
IN NEWTOWN.
HE ALSO HAD AN OLDER BROTHER,
RYAN, WHO WE'RE TOLD HAD
STOPPED SPEAKING WITH MISS
BROTHER, SOMEWHERE ALONG THE
LINE ABOUT TWO YEARS AGO.
WHY?
AGAIN, ANOTHER QUESTION THAT
CERTAINLY WILL COME OUT IN A
COUPLE OF DAYS, BUT TODAY THE
PRESIDENT WILL VISIT NEWTOWN.
I'M ATTEND A VIGIL HONORING
THE VICTIMS.
WE'RE ALSO LEARNING NEW
DETAILS ABOUT THE
INVESTIGATION, KELLY.
PETER DOOCY IS GOING TO JOIN
US LIVE RIGHT NOW.
HE'S AT THE SCENE IN NEWTOWN
WITH THE LATEST DETAILS WHAT'S
BEEN UNFOLDING THERE IN THE
PAST 24 HOURS.
>> ONE OF THE HARDEST THINGS
TO LOOK AT IN NEWTOWN IS THE
SPREAD SHEET PROVIDED BY THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER THAT LISTS
THE NAMES AND BIRTHDAYS OF THE
VICTIMS, MANY BORN IN 2006 AND
2005 AND THE THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER SAYS THAT EVERYONE
SHOT WAS SHOT BETWEEN THREE
AND 11 TIMES WITH A BUSH
MASTER SEMI AUTOMATIC RIFLE
AND EVERY O THAT
MEDICAL EXAMINER SHARED MADE
THIS TERRIBLE CRIME EVEN
HARDER TO HANDSEL.
>> THEY WERE FIRST GRADERS,
INTO KID STUFF.
THE KIND OF STUFF YOU'D SEND
YOUR KIDS AND GRANDKIDS TO,
FIRST GRADERS.
>> FEDERAL AGENTS TODAY WILL
VISIT LOCAL RETAILERS AT
SHOOTING RANGES, TRYING TO
FIGURE OUT WHO ADAM LANZA KNEW
AND WE DID HEAR FROM ADAM
LANZA'S AUNT IN ILLINOIS
YESTERDAY WHO TOLD US THAT HIS
MOTHER NANCY KEPT A LOT OF
GUNS IN THE HOUSE FOR
SELF-DEFENSE.
>> AND FOR SELF-DEFENSE, NO
OTHER REASON.
THEY WERE NOT A VIOLENT
FAMILY.
THEY WERE NOT ONE TO, YOU
KNOW, SHE HAD IT DEFINITELY
WOULD HAVE BEEN FOR
SELF-DEFENSE BECAUSE SHE DID
LIVE ALONE.
>> 26 CHRISTMAS TREES, ONE FOR
EVERY TEACHER AND EVERY
STUDENT WHO WERE KILLED INSIDE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
WERE JUST DELIVERED AND SET UP
ON THE ROAD TO SANDY HOOK,
DONATED BY AN ANONYMOUS PERSON
SOMEWHERE IN NORTH CAROLINA,
THE SUPPORT NATIONALLY AND
LOCALLY FOR THE VICTIMS AND
THOSE FAMILIES AFFECTED BY
THIS TRAGEDY HAS BEEN
TREMENDOUS, BUT FROM WHAT WE
CAN TELL SO FAR, IT'S REALLY
NOT MAKING PEOPLE FEEL ANY
BETTER JUST YET.
BACK TO YOU IN NEW YORK.
>> PETER, THANK YOU FOR AT
THAT REPORT.
AND SO MUCH IS GOING ON IN
THIS COMMUNITY AND WE'RE
FINDING IS ACTUALLY BRINGING
ITSELF TOGETHER.
AND IT HAS TO IN ORDER TO MOVE
FORWARD.
AND YOU GUYS ARE FROM
CONNECTICUT, HOW WOULD YOU
DESCRIBE CONNECTICUT?
WHAT KIND OF PLACE?
>> WELL, I MEAN, NEWTOWN
CONNECTICUT IS YOU KNOW, THIS
VERY PRECIOUS, BEAUTIFUL
LITTLE NEW ENGLAND TOWN.
I SPENT A CHRISTMAS EVE GOING
TO A MIDNIGHT MASS THERE ONE
TIME WHEN I WAS A TEENAGER AND
HAD BEEN AN INTELABLE IMAGE
FOR ME SINCE IN MY LIFE.
IT WAS CHARMING AND BEAUTIFUL
AND TWINKLING AND CHURCH
BELLS, IT'S THAT KIND OF TOWN.
>> Dave: WELL, AND CONNECTICUT
TO GIVE YOU INSIGHT, PEOPLE
THINK OF THE EAST COAST AND
THINK OF NEW YORK AND
PHILADELPHIA AND BOSTON AND
CONNECTICUT IS MADE UP OF
TOWNS LIKE NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
IT'S ALMOST ENTIRELY, 10, 20,
30,000 PERSON TOWNS LIKE THE
ONES THAT ALISYN AND I BOTH
LIVE IN.
AND MANY ACROSS THE STATE AND
WHAT IT'S MADE UP OF.
AND WHY WE FEEL IT COULD BE
ANYONE.
>> Kelly: AND THE CULTURE
THERE, KNOWING YOUR NEIGHBOR
AND SPEAKING OF CULTURE AND
MIKE HUCKABEE WHO IS A DEAR
FRIEND OF OURS AND HAS HIS OWN
PROGRAM ON THIS NETWORK, MIKE
WAS TALKING ABOUT THE ROLE OF
GOD IN OUR SOCIETY AS RELATES
TO OUR CULTURE.
LET'S LISTEN TO WHAT MIKE WAS
TALKING ABOUT ON "FOX &
FRIENDS" HERE YESTERDAY.
>> YESTERDAY, I WAS ON NEIL
CAVUTO AND HE ASKED ME WHERE
WAS GOD AND I SAID WE'VE
SYSTEMATICALLY REMOVED HIM
FROM OUR CULTURE AND SCHOOLS,
AND I'VE BEEN BARRAGED BY
PEOPLE WHO SAID IF WE HAVE
PRAYER IN SCHOOLS THIS WOULD
NOT HAPPEN.
THAT'S NOT MY POINT.
IF WE AS A CULTURE DECIDED
THAT WE DON'T WANT TO HAVE
VALUES THAT WE DON'T WANT TO
SAY THAT SOME THINGS ARE
ALWAYS RIGHT, SOME THINGS ARE
ALWAYS WRONG WHEN WE DIVORCE
OURSELVES FROM A BASIC SENSE
OF WHAT WE WOULD CALL, I WOULD
SAY, COLLECTIVE MORALITY WHERE
WE AGREE ON CERTAIN PRINCIPLES
TO BE TRUE ALWAYS, THEN WE, WE
CREATE A CULTURE, NOT THAT IT
SPECIFICALLY CREATES THIS
CRIME, IT DOESN'T.
BUT IT CREATES AN ATMOSPHERE
IN WHICH EVIL AND VIOLENCE ARE
REMOVED FROM OUR SENSE OF
RESPONSIBILITY.
>> Kelly: CAN I JUST ADD
QUICKLY TO THAT.
AT THE EXPENSE OF BEING
BARRAGED, I UNDERSTAND WHAT
MIKE IS TALKING ABOUT HERE,
WE'RE CUT THE SAME CLOTH HERE.
THERE WAS A TIME WE HAD PRAYER
IN SCHOOL AND THE ONLY PROBLEM
GUM, CHEWING GUM AND TOO MUCH
TALKING IN THE CLASSROOM.
TODAY, WE'VE GOT ARMED GUARDS
PROTECTING OUR STUDENTS, AND
WE HAVE GUNS IN THE SCHOOL,
THAT'S A PROBLEM.
>> Alisyn: LOOK, EVERYONE
TODAY I THINK IS CASTING ABOUT
FOR THEORIES ON WHAT COULD
CAUSE THIS, EVERYBODY IS
DESPERATE TO TRY TO FIGURE OUT
HOW TO PREVENT IT FROM
HAPPENING AGAIN.
AND MIKE HUCKABEE BELIEVES
IT'S THE CULTURE AND WE'VE
HEARD PEOPLE FROM ALL
DIFFERENT WALKS OF LIFE AND
SOME PEOPLE SAY MENTAL HEALTH
ISSUES AND SOME ABOUT GUNS.
WE NEED TO HAVE THE
CONVERSATION AND CRACK THE
CORRODE.
>> Kelly: ALL OF THE ABOVE.
>> Dave: PEOPLE ON TWITTER
SAYING THAT STATES ARE CUTTING
BACK MENTAL HEALTH CARE
SERVICES AND THAT'S FNOT GOING
TO MAKE IT BETTER.
WE'LL BE LIVE IN WASHINGTON
NEXT TO TALK TO FOX NEWS
SUNDAY HOST CHRIS WALLACE WITH
MORE ON THE REACTION FROM THE
PRESIDENT AND FROM CAPITOL
HILL.
♪
[ Mother ]
YOU CAN'T LEAVE THE TABLE
TILL YOU FINISH YOUR VEGETABLES.
[ clock ticking ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THERE'S A BETTER WAY...
V8 V-FUSION.
VEGETABLE NUTRITION THEY NEED,
FRUIT TASTE THEY LOVE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
OR...TRY KIDS BOXES!
often comes with a set
of equally impressive
instructions ?
Shouldn't something
that's truly advanced,
not need much explanation
at all ?
With the Nokia Lumia 822
on Verizon,
there's not much to learn
because it's
powered by Windows...
to let you do more than you ever
imagined on your smartphone.
Exclusively with Data Sense--
a feature that makes
the most of your plan.
Only on Verizon.
>>  THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES AND FIVE AND TEN
YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
>> Alisyn: THE PRESIDENT AT
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT THIS WILL
BE THE FOURTH VISIT TO A CITY
FOLLOWING A MASS SHOOTING.
LET'S BRING IN CHRIS WALLACE,
HOST OF FOX NEWS SUNDAY.
>> Kelly: GOOD MORNING, CHRIS.
>> I HAVE TO SAY I'VE BEEN
COVERING PRESIDENTS AND IN THE
BRIEFING ROOM AT THE WHITE
HOUSE MORE THAN 30 YEARS AND
NEVER SAW A MOMENT LIKE THAT
OF THAT KIND OF SHEER EMOTION
AND BROUGHT FORWARD HOW
TERRIBLE THIS PARTICULAR ONE
WAS.
>> Kelly: I HAVE TO AGREE WITH
YOU, WHEN THE PRESIDENT SPOKE
AND EVEN NOW, STILL GRIPS HE
ME EMOTIONALLY, BECAUSE HERE
IS THE COMMANDER-IN-CHIEF NOW
SERVING AS A CONSOLER IN CHIEF
AND HE REALLY SHOWED RAW
EMOTION AND TOOK A MINUTE FOR
HIM TO HOLD THAT BACK AND
ACTUALLY MOVE ON WITH HIS
STATEMENT.
>> WELL, THAT'S RIGHT AND AS
HE SAID, HE WAS NOT RESPONDING
AS A PRESIDENT, BUT AS A
PARENT, HE OF COURSE THE
FATHER OF TWO YOUNG CHILDREN
AND I DON'T KNOW THAT YOU HAVE
TO HAVE CHILDREN, BUT IF YOU
DO, AND IF YOU REMEMBER THOSE
DAYS WHEN YOU SENT THEM OFF TO
SCHOOL AS SIX AND SEVEN YEAR
OLDS WITH ALL OF THEIR BRIGHT
HOPES AND LEARNING TO READ AND
LEARNING TO ADD AND SUBTRACT
THE IDEA OF THEM BEING STRUCK
DOWN IS PARTICULARLY AWFUL.
>> Dave: TODAY ON YOUR SHOW
YOU HAVE CONNECTICUT SENATOR
JOE LIEBERMAN TO TALK ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED AT SANDY HOOK
AND ALSO SOME OF THE PARENTS
THERE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY, I'M CURIOUS,
CHRIS, ONLY BECAUSE YOUR SHOW
IS ONE THAT TYPICALLY DEALS
ENTIRELY WITH POLITICS, AT
WHAT POINT DO YOU FEEL THAT
WASHINGTON GETS BACK TO THE
BUSINESS OF AVOIDING THIS
FISCAL CLIFF NOW THAT JOHN
BOEHNER HAS APPARENTLY
REPORTEDLY FLOAT A PROPOSAL
THAT WOULD LIKE A TAX ON THOSE
MAKING A MILLION DOLLARS OR
MORE.
THERE'S NOT A LOT OF TIME,
OBVIOUSLY DON'T WANT TO APPEAR
INSENSITIVE, BUT NOT A LOT OF
TIME BEFORE ALL OF THIS
CHANGES AND WE DO GO OVER THAT
CLIFF.
>> LOOK, A GREAT NATION CAN DO
MORE THAN ONE THING AT A TIME,
DAVE.
AND PEOPLE HERE CAN ABSOLUTELY
FEEL AS DEEPLY AS THE
PRESIDENT EXPRESSED THERE ON
FRIDAY ABOUT THE LAWS, BUT ALL
OF US, YOU KNOW, GO ABOUT OUR
JOBS, GO ABOUT OUR BUSINESS,
GO ABOUT OUR LIVES AND THAT'S
THE JOB OF THE PEOPLE HERE IN
WASHINGTON IS TO TRY TO FIND
SOME WAY TO AVOID THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
AS YOU SAY, THERE WAS A TRIAL
BALLOON FLOATED THIS WEEKEND,
AT FIRST DENIED AND THEN
CONFIRMED THAT SPEAKER BOEHNER
IS NOW GIVING IN ON RATES, BUT
NOT FOR PEOPLE AT $250,000,
FOR PEOPLE AT A MILLION, BUT
NEEDS TO SEE SOMETHING MUCH
MORE SERIOUS FOR THE PRESIDENT
ON SPENDING CUTS.
YOU SAY HOW SOON DO THEY GET
BACK TO IT?
THEY HAVE HE GOT TO BE GETTING
BACK TO IT RIGHT NOW BECAUSE
TWO WEEKS FROM TUESDAY WE'LL
GO OVER THE CLIFF.
THAT'S ONE OF THE ISSUES AND
THE OTHER IS, THERE'S GOING TO
BE A COUPLE OF HEARINGS, ONE
IN THE HOUSE, ONE IN THE
SENATE, ABOUT THE SENATE
DEPARTMENT INVESTIGATION INTO
THE BENGHAZI CONSULATE ATTACK.
AND SECRETARY OF STATE CLINTON
WAS SUPPOSED TO TESTIFY AT
BOTH OF THOSE, BUT NOW SHE'S
AT THE--
SHE HAD STOMACH VIRUS, SHE
FAINTED AND THAT SHE SUFFERED
A CONCUSSION, SO SHE WILL NOT
SPEAK TO THOSE--
TESTIFY BEFORE THOSE
COMMITTEES THIS WEEK, HER TOP
DEPUTY WILL.
>> Alisyn: CHRIS, THANKS FOR
PREVIEWING WHAT'S ON YOUR SHOW
ON THIS TOUGH SUNDAY.
>> THANKS.
>> Dave: AND JOHN KERRY
POTENTIAL SECRETARY OF STATE?
WILL HE BE EASILY CONFIRMED.
>> Kelly: WHILE WE TALK ABOUT
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON, ALL OF OUR HOPE THAT
SHE'LL GET BACK IN TIP TOP
SHAPE AND THAT WAS QUITE A
FALL AND HITTING HER HEAD AND
HER STOMACH VIRUS NAGGED HER
AND SHE HAD TO CANCEL TRIPS,
BUT MANY QUESTIONS GETTING
BACK TO WHERE WE ARE TODAY
ABOUT THE STATE OF OUR CULTURE
AFTER THIS TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN.
IS IT JUST TOO VIOLENT OF A
SOCIETY THAT WE LIVE IN TODAY?
SHOULD THIS SERVE AS A WAKEUP
CALL FOR ALL OF US TO FIND
SOME CHANGE?
THAT'S NEXT.
♪
>>  I'VE BEEN AT THIS FOR A
THIRD OF A CENTURY AND IT'S MY
SENSEABILITIES MAY NOT BE THE
AVERAGE MAN'S, BUT THIS
PROBABLY IS THE WORST I HAVE
SE
SEEN.
>> Kelly: THAT OF COURSE WAS
THE STATE MEDICAL EXAMINER, A
SEASONED MEDICAL EXAMINER
REACTING TO THE TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT AND VISIBLY
SHOWING HIS EMOTION AS WELL.
MEANWHILE, WE'RE LEARNING NEW
DETAILS ABOUT THE GUNMAN, ADAM
LANZA, HE MAY HAVE SUFFERED
FROM A PERSONALITY DISORDER IT
SEEMS AND APPARENTLY AN AVID
VIDEO GAME PLAYER.
SO, IS THERE SOMETHING IN OUR
CULTURE THAT COULD BE TO BLAME
FOR THIS VIOLENCE?
THAT'S THE QUESTION WE'RE
ASKING NOW AND JOINING US IS
FORMER WEB POINT PSYCHOLOGY
PROFESSOR, AN AUTHOR ON
KILLING.
LT. COLONEL DAVID GROSSMAN AND
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US
TODAY.
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY ABOUT THIS
PARTICULAR CASE?
WE UNDERSTAND THAT FROM FORMER
CLASSMATES OF ADAM LANZA THAT
HE WAS A LONER.
SOME DESCRIBED HIM AS BEING
SMART, BUT KIND OF A NERD AND
NOT HAVING MANY FRIENDS, BUT
THE FRIENDS HE DID HAVE
INDICATED THAT HE PLAYED VIDEO
GAMES, DEADLY VIDEO GAMES
DEALING WITH VIOLENCE AND
WOULD THIS HAVE PLAYED A ROLE
IN PERHAPS HIS PSYCHE OR HIS
EMOTIONS?
>> OKAY.
THE KIDS AT THE JONESBORO
MIDDLE SCHOOL.
VIRGINIA TECH COLLEGE, GAVE US
THAT MASSACRE ON THE ISLAND IN
NORWAY, THEY GAVE US A MALL
MASSACRE IN AURORA, COLORADO,
JONESBORO, COLUMBINE, VIRGINIA
TECH, THIS IS JUST THE
BEGINNING.
WHAT YOU SAW IN NEWTOWN IS
JUST THE BEGINNING.
THIS IS A SICK, SICK CULTURE,
SICK MOVIES AND SICK VIDEO
GAMES CREATING VERY, VERY SICK
KIDS.
I TRAINED MILITARY AND LAW
ENFORCEMENT WORLDWIDE, I'M ON
THE ROAD 300 DAYS A YEAR
TRAINING MOSTLY COPS, OF OUR
NATION'S LEADING LAW
ENFORCEMENT TRAINER GO TO
WWW.GET BULLET-PROOF.COM AND I
PREDICTED THIS IS GOING TO
HAPPEN.
IT'S A TREND.
I MEAN, LOOK AT THE PAST.
JONESBORO, COLUMBINE, VIRGINIA
TECH, AND NOW THIS.
AND DON'T FORGET AURORA, IN
BELGIUM THIS SICKO GOT IN A
DAY CARE CENTER AND HACKED 12
MILL BABIES IN THE CRIB.
AROUND THE PLANET.
>> Kelly: COLONEL.
>>G UNCOMFORTABLE
CRIMES, THIS IS NOT NORMAL,
IT'S NOT NORMAL FOR EVERY KID
IN AMERICA TO HUNKER DOWN AND
KIDS COME TO KILL THEM.
>> Kelly: COLONEL.
>> IT'S NOT NORMAL FOR EVERY
COP TO--
TO PRACTICE AND GO INTO THE
KILLING OUR KIDS.
>> Kelly: LET ME GET IN A WORD
EDGE-WISE FOR A MOMENT.
I SEE AND FEEL YOUR PASSION
AND I SO MUCH AGREE WITH YOU
ON THE PAIN, BUT THE POINT IS,
HOW DO WE MOVE FORWARD?
I MEAN, WHAT DO WE DO IN TERMS
OF ADDRESSING THESE VIDEO
GAMES THAT YOU'RE TALKING
ABOUT.
I DON'T WANT TO MENTION THEIR
NAMES, BUT THERE ARE GAMES OUT
THERE THAT REALLY TEACH PEOPLE
HOW TO KILL, ACCORDING TO YOUR
REPORTS AND THE REPORTS FROM
MILITARY AND LAW ENFORCEMENT.
SO, HOW DO WE GET BEYOND THIS
WHEN THESE GAMES ARE MAKING
MULTIPLE MILLIONS OF DOLLARS?
>> IT'S AN ABSOLUTE RAW
BEGINNING.
AND I OUTLINED THIS IN OUR
VIDEOS TO COPS NATIONWIDE,
WWW.GET BULLET-PROOF MIND.COM.
I OUTLINED IT WORLDWIDE AND
WE'VE GOT TO ENFORCE THE
RATING SYSTEM.
M-RATED GAME AND NY 17 IF YOU
HAVE PARTIES AND LET THE KIDS
WATCH X-RATED VIDEO GAMES AND
LET AND HAVE YOUR KIDS SIT AND
WATCH M RATED VIDEO GAMES.
AND NC 17, NO CHILD UNDER 17,
X-RATED VIDEO GAMES AND SICK,
SICK GAMES AND MANUFACTURERS
SAY THAT CHILDREN SHOULDN'T BE
PLAYING THESE GAMES.
>> Kelly: PARENTS SHOULD BE
MORE RESPONSIBLE THEN AND
PROACTIVE.
>> AND FOR THE PARENTS TO BE
RESPONSIBLE THEY'VE GOT TO BE
ENVELOPED AND WE'VE GOT TO
TELL THEM IF YOU'RE PLAYING
THESE SICK GAMES AND LETTING
YOUR CHILDREN DO IT, THERE'S
ALL KINDS OF THINGS ADULTS CAN
DO, BUT CAN'T.
GAMBLING, PORNOGRAPHY,
TOBACCO, ALCOHOL, FIREARMS,
SEX, DRUGS, AUTOMOBILES.
THERE ARE ALL KINDS OF THINGS
ADULTS CAN DO AND CHILDREN
CAN'T THE AND VIOLENT VISUAL
IMAGERY.
AND WE MUST ENFORCE THEM.
MY CHILD CAN PLAY A VIDEO
GAME.
NO, HE CAN'T.
ENFORCE THE RATINGS.
AND THIS IS THE BEGINNING,
DON'T LOOK AT THIS IN
ISOLATION AND DON'T PULL YOUR
HAIR OUT AND FORGET JONESBORO,
COLUMBINE, VIRGINIA TECH OR
MASSACRE IN AURORA.
LOOK AT THEM AS A GROWING
MOVING TREND AND IT'S GOING TO
GET WORSE.
I KNOW HOW TO TEACH PEOPLE TO
KILL, THAT'S MY JOB AND THE
VIDEO GAMES ARE PROVIDING THE
TRAINING, THE DESENSITIZATION
AND THE CONDITIONED RESPONSES,
CONDITIONING, AND OFFERS
CONDITIONING, BEING FED TO
CHILDREN THAT'S IDENTICAL TO
WHAT WE DO TO MILITARY AND LAW
ENFORCEMENT.
>> Kelly: COLONEL, YOU TALK
ABOUT TRAINING, WHAT ABOUT
THOSE WHO ARE UNTRAINED.
CAN THEY ALSO WATCH THESE
GAMES AND PERHAPS FROM THAT
GATHER TRAINING AND SOME SORT
OF--
>> ABSOLUTELY, THESE ARE POINT
AND SHOOT VIDEO GAMES WHICH
REHEARSE THE ACTION OF
SHOOTING AND KILLING.
YOU MENTALLY REHEARSE THE
ACTION OF SHOOTING YOUR
VICTIMS, SHOOT THEM IN THE
HEAD, SHOOT THEM ALL TWICE AND
WE CAN IDENTIFY THE VIDEO GAME
THAT THE KID PLAYED IN ORDER
TO DOUBLE TAP THE VICTIMS EACH
AND MAKE THEM DEAD, BUT IT
DOESN'T TAKE A LOT OF SKILL TO
WALK UP TO A CHILD AND SHOVE A
GUN IN THEIR FACE AND BLOW
THEIR BRAINS OUT WHAT IT TAKES
IS DESENSITIZATION AND
CONDITIONING TO DO IT AGAIN
AND AGAIN AND AGAIN, TO DO IT
IN JONESBORO, COLUMBINE AND
VIRGINIA TECH WHAT, DO THEY
HAVE IN COMMON, THEY DROP DOWN
AND IMMERSE IN THE SICKEST
MOVIES AND SICKEST VIDEO GAMES
AND GUYS, NEVER FORGET I TOLD
YOU, THIS IS JUST THE
BEGINNING.
WE HAVE RAISED A GENERATION OF
CHILDREN WHO HAVE LEARNED TO
KILL AND LEARNED TO LIKE IT.
AND WHEN WE GET A SICK KID IN
PAST YEARS THEY WERE CHEWING
GUM AND TALKING OUT IN CLASS.
NOW WE CREATED SICK KIDS AND
THEY'RE GOING TO COME KILL
YOU.
IF YOU'RE THE PARENTS WHO LET
THE KIDS PLAY THE SICK GAMES,
THE BLOODS IS ON YOUR HAND AND
BY THE WAY YOU MIGHT BE THE
FIRST TO DIE AS WHAT HAPPENED
HERE.
>> Kelly: COLONEL, IT'S VERY
SOBERING WHAT YOU MENTIONED
AND SOBERING THOUGHTS AND
HOPEFULLY PEOPLE TALKING AND
TAKING HEED AND EVEN HOST WHO
MAY DISAGREE.
BUT TAKE IT TO HEART AND THERE
ARE SO MANY THINGS WE HAVE TO
DISCUSS, MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES,
FAITH ISSUES, CULTURE ISSUES
AND EVEN THE ISSUES OF VIDEO
GAMES THAT TEACH CHILDREN TO
BE DESENSITIZED AND THAT'S
LIEUTENANT DAVE GROSSMAN
FORMER WEST POINT PSYCHOLOGY
PROFESSOR AND THE AUTHOR OF
"ON KILLING."  WE THANK YOU
FOR JOINING US.
WELL, AS WE CONTINUE OUR
COVERAGE, THE STORIES OF
HEROES EMERGING FROM THE
TRAGEDIES, A PRINCIPAL SO
DEDICATED, SHE RAN TOWARDS THE
GUNMAN, CAN YOU IMAGINE,
TRYING TO SAVE HER STUDENTS
AND HER FELLOW TEACHERS.
WE'LL HEAR FROM A VERY GOOD
FRIENDS OF THE BELOVED
PRINCIPAL.
THAT AND MORE NEXT.
♪
WELCOME BACK EVERYONE ON THIS
VERY SAD DAY AND WE APPRECIATE
YOU SPENDING THE TIME WITH US
AND SEEING THE NAMES
JUXTAPOSED WITH THE AGES,
JUST, TAKES YOUR BREATH AWAY
TO SEE HOW YOUNG MOST OF THE
CHILDREN ARE.
>> Dave: ALL THE CHILDREN SIX
AND SEVEN YEARS OLD.
DIFFICULT TO SEE THE NAMES AND
FAR MORE DIFFICULT WHEN YOU
SEE SOME OF THE PICTURES WE'RE
GETTING TO SEE WHEN YOU REALLY
CAN PICTURE A BEAUTIFUL YOUNG
SIX OR SEVEN-YEAR-OLD BOY AND
HOW DIFFICULT THIS MUST BE FOR
THE PARENTS AND EDUCATORS
INVOLVED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> Kelly: THEY WERE SO FULL OF
LIFE AND HAD SO MANY THINGS TO
LOOK FORWARD TO AND SADLY,
THAT IS NOT GOING TO HAPPEN.
SO, WHEN YOU LOOK AT THE
SITUATION YOU'RE ALSO LOOKING
AT THE TEACHERS AS WELL AND
THE ROLE THEY PLAYED IN
PROTECTING A LOT OF THEIR
STUDENTS WITH THEIR OWN LIVES
AND THE PROFILE OF THE
PRINCIPAL, FOR EXAMPLE,
DEDICATED TO HER SCHOOL.
DEDICATED TO EDUCATION, THIS
WAS, I WOULD HAVE TO SAY, A
TEACHERS'S TEACHER, A
PRINCIPAL OF PRINCIPALS WHO
REALLY CARED SO DEEPLY, NOT
ONLY FOR HER STUDENTS AND
FELLOW TEACHERS, BUT HER
COMMUNITY.
>> Alisyn: SHE HAD AN ACTIVE
TWITTER STREAM AND
COMMUNICATED WITH THE PARENTS
AND KIDS AND ONE AUGUST 24TH
OF THIS YEAR, THE FIRST DAY OF
SCHOOL SHE SAID, WELCOMING OUR
KINDERGARTENERS THIS MORNING,
74 NEW OPPORTUNITIES TO
INSPIRE LIFE-LONG LEARNING.
WE HAD A CHANCE TO TALK WITH
ONE OF OTHER CLOSE FRIENDS.
>> Dave: DAWN HOCHSPRUNG WE'RE
TALKING ABOUT AND SHE WENT TO
THE SHOOTER TO PROTECT HER
STUDENTS AND BEFORE THAT, DAWN
WAS ONE THAT WANTED TO UPGRADE
THE SECURITY SYSTEM AT THAT
SCHOOL AND IMAGINED A
SITUATION EERILY SIMILAR TO
WHAT UNFOLDED AND PREPARE
HERSELF FOR WHAT WOULD HAPPEN.
AND SHE WAS THE ONE WHO WOULD
CONFRONT A SHOOTER.
AND WE SPOKE TO ONE OF HER
CLOSE FRIENDS IN WOODBURY,
CONNECTICUT, GERALD, ABOUT HIS
CLOSE FRIEND ABOUT A CARING
AND DEDICATED EDUCATOR.
>> SHE KNEW THAT THE HEALTH
AND SAFETY OF HER CHILDREN
WERE ABSOLUTELY PARAMOUNT.
I THINK THAT WE, THE THING
THAT WE NEED TO COME AWAY FROM
THIS IS THE FACT THAT SHE
ACTUALLY SAVED A GREAT MANY
LIVES AND TAKING THE ACTIONS
THAT SHE DID.
THIS SHOOTER HAD THE
CAPABILITY OF KILLING MUCH
MORE.
THIS TRAGEDY WOULD HAVE BEEN
FAR WORSE IF IT WASN'T FOR HER
HEROIC ACTIONS.
WHEN WE TALK ABOUT THESE TYPES
OF THINGS IN OUR WILDEST
DREAMS, DID WE EVER THINK THAT
THE REALITY OF THIS
CONVERSATION THAT HER AND I
HAD WOULD ACTUALLY UNFOLDED
INTO REALITY AND THEN CAUSING
THE LOSS OF HER LIFE?
SHE IS TRULY A HERO TODAY.
>> Dave: SHE'S ALSO SOMEONE
WHO WANTED TO HAVE A LOT OF
FUN THERE IN SCHOOL.
SHE STARTED WHACKY WEDNESDAYS
WHERE THE THE KIDS WOULD WEAR
MISMATCHED CLOTHING ALTHOUGH
MANY OF OUR KIDS DO THAT EVERY
DAY.
AND SHE WANTED EVERYONE TO
WEAR MISMATCHED CLOTHING ON
WEDNESDAYS AND SHE EVEN
PARTICIPATED AND I'M SURE
THAT'S A TRADITION THAT NEVER
WENT AWAY AT SANDY HOOK.
>> Alisyn: SHE WAS BELOVED.
AND THE KIDS WHO THANKFULLY
SURVIVED.
HOW DO THEY GO ABOUT TELLING
THEIR CHILDREN THAT THE
PRINCIPAL IS GONE.
ONE MOTHER OF A FOURTH GRADER
WAS GRAPPLING WITH THAT.
>> HE SAID EVERYONE AT MY
SCHOOL ARE DEAD.
I SAID, NO, THE KIDS--
HE SAID THE SCHOOL IS DEAD.
AND MRS. HOCHSPRUNG IS NOT
GOING TO BE THERE AND WE'LL
KNOW WHEN WE GO TO SCHOOL AND
THE SCHOOL FOR ME IS DEAD AND
I THINK IT'S NEVER GOING TO BE
THE SAME.
>> Dave: YOU DO WONDER WHAT
THEY'LL DO AT THAT SCHOOL AND
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
CERTAINLY NO SCHOOL THIS WEEK
BEFORE CHRISTMAS BREAK AND
THEN TIME, BUT WHEN WILL THE
KIDS BE READY TO GO BACK
INSIDE A PLACE THEY ONCE
THOUGHT WAS COMPLETELY SAFE.
NO TELLING IF THEY'LL BE ABLE
TO DO THAT AGAIN THIS YEAR.
>> YOU'RE RIGHT, DAVE.
AND THIS PARTICULAR PARENT
UNDERSCORES THE REASON WHY YOU
NEED SO MUCH GRIEF COUNSELING
IN THAT SCHOOL, THROUGHOUT THE
ENTIRE COMMUNITY BECAUSE THIS
ENTIRE COMMUNITY BECAUSE OF
ITS SMALLNESS IN POPULATION
AND CLOSE PROXIMITY TO JUST
BEING A CLOSE KNIT COMMUNITY,
THEY'RE GOING TO NEED A LOT OF
HELP.
>> Alisyn: WAS COLUMBINE TORN
DOWN.
>> Dave: NO, STAYED OPEN, SAME
NAME.
>> Alisyn: IS THAT RIGHT?
>> A VERY SUCCESSFUL HIGH
SCHOOL TO THIS DAY.
>> Alisyn: AND MEANWHILE,
PRESIDENT OBAMA OF COURSE
STRESSING THE NEED TO COME
TOGETHER AS A COUNTRY TO MOURN
THE VICTIMS OF THIS MASSACRE
REGARDLESS OF WHERE WE ALL
LIVE.
>> ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, A SHOPPING MALL IN
OREGON, A HOUSE OF WORSHIP IN
WISCONSIN, A MOVIE THEATER IN
COLORADO, COUNTLESS STREET
CORNERS IN PLACES LIKE CHICAGO
AND PHILADELPHIA, ANY OF THESE
NEIGHBORHOODS COULD BE OUR
OWN.
>> AND TONIGHT, THE PRESIDENT
WILL ATTEND A VIGIL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
TRAVELLING THERE THIS
AFTERNOON TO HONOR THE VICTIMS
OF COURSE THE 20 CHILDREN WE
HAVE BEEN TALKING ABOUT.
>> Kelly: MOLLY HENNEBERG NOW
FROM WASHINGTON, WITH MORE
DETAILS ON THE PRESIDENT'S
PLAN.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
>> Reporter:  KELLY, ALISYN,
DAVE, GOOD MORNING.
TODAY THE PRESIDENT WILL
CONVEY THE ANGUISH OF A NATION
AS HE TRAVELS TO NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THE WHITE HOUSE JUST ANNOUNCED
THE TRIP LATE YESTERDAY.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL SPEAK
PRIVATELY WITH VICTIMS'
FAMILIES AND ALSO THANK
EMERGENCY RESPONDERS LATER
TODAY AND THEN THIS EVENING
HE'LL ATTEND AN INTERFAITH
MEMORIAL SERVICE HONORING
THOSE WHO WERE MURDERED.
IN HIS WEEKLY RADIO AND
INTERNET ADDRESS THIS WEEKEND,
THE PRESIDENT MOURNED THE LOSS
OF THE TEACHERS AND CHILDREN.
>> WHILE NOTHING CAN TAKE THE
PLACE OF A LOST CHILD OR LOVED
ONE, ALL THAT CAN EXTEND A
HAND TO THOSE IN NEED, TO
REMIND THEM THAT WE'RE THERE
FOR THEM AND PRAY FOR THEM AND
THE LOVE THEY FELT FOR THOSE
LOST NOT ONLY JUST IN THEIR
MEMORIES, BUT ALSO IN THEIR
COMMUNITIES AND IN THEIR
COUNTRY.
>> THIS IS THE FOURTH TIME
SINCE HE BECAME PRESIDENT THAT
MR. OBAMA WILL TRAVEL TO A
COMMUNITY REELING FROM A MASS
SHOOTING.
LAST YEAR TO COLORADO AFTER A
SHOOTING SPREE IN A MOVIE
THEATER.
YOU SEE SOME OF THAT VIDEO
NOW.
IN 2011, WENT TO ARIZONA AFTER
A GUNMAN SHOT AND KILLED SIX
MORE AND SHOT CONGRESSWOMAN
GABRIEL GIFFORDS.
THE PRESIDENT SAID THE
COUNTRIES NEEDS TO TAKE MORE
ACTION TO PRE HE VENT
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS REFERRING
TO MORE GUN CONTROL LAWS, BACK
TO YOU IN NEW YORK.
>> Dave: AND THE PRESIDENT WAS
JUST HERE TRYING TO CONSOLE
THOSE SUFFERING FROM HURRICANE
SANDY AND STILL REBUILDING
THIS MORNING, SO IT HASN'T
BEEN AN EASY TIME FOR THE
PRESIDENT IN THIS REGION.
>> Alisyn: CERTAINLY.
WE DO HAVE TWO OTHER HEADLINES
TO TELL, BUT RIGHT NOW.
ON THE DAY OF THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL MASSACRE, POLICE IN
OKLAHOMA BELIEVE IT OR NOT
STOPPED ANOTHER MASSACRE FROM
HAPPENING.
18-YEAR-OLD SANDY CHAVEZ WAS
ARRESTED ON FRIDAY, POLICE SAY
HE WAS RECRUITING CLASSMATES
TO LURE OTHER STUDENTS INTO
THE AUDITORIUM WHERE HE
PLANNED TO CHAIN THE DOORS AND
OPEN FIRE.
AND HE ALSO WANTED TO PUT
BOMBS ON THE DOORS TO GO OFF
WHEN POLICE ARRIVED.
ANOTHER STUDENT ALERTED POLICE
TO THAT PLOT.
AND IN WASHINGTON ON AVOIDING
THE FISCAL CLIFF.
FOX NEWS LEARNED THAT SPEAKER
BOEHNER, PEOPLE MAKING ONE
MILLION DOLLARS A YEAR.
>> WASHINGTON HAS HAD A
SPENDING PROBLEM THAT CAN'T BE
FIXED WITH TAX INCREASES
ALONE.
THE PRESIDENT WILL STEP UP AND
SHOW US HE'S WILLING TO MAKE
THE SPENDING CUTS THAT ARE
NEEDED, I THINK WE COULD DO
SOME REAL GOOD IN THE DAYS
AHEAD.
>> Alisyn: SO FAR NO RESPONSE
FROM THE WHITE HOUSE ON HIS
OFFER.
AND WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO
KEEP WAITING TO GET ANSWERS
FROM SECRETARY OF STATE
HILLARY CLINTON ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED IN BENGHAZI ON
SEPTEMBER 11TH.
SHE WILL NOT BE ABLE TO
TESTIFY THIS WEEK IN FRONT OF
CONGRESS.
CLINTON IS IT RECOVERING FROM
A CONCUSSION AFTER FAINTING ON
A TRIP FROM DEHYDRATION SHE'S
BEEN SUFFERING FROM A STOMACH
VIRUS.
TWO OF CLINTON'S DEPUTIES WILL
TESTIFY IN HER PLACE AS
LAWMAKERS TRY TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT WENT WRONG AT THE U.S.
CONSULATE LEAVING FOUR
AMERICANS DEAD.
DAVE, I KNOW YOU KNOW THE
CONNECTION BETWEEN THE
TRAGEDIES AND THE OUTPOURING.
>> Dave: IT IS INTERSECTING
THIS WEEKEND, THE TRAGEDY
SHOCKED THE WORLD AND THE
SPORTS WORLD, NOT EXCLUDED.
LEBRON JAMES, AND THE MIAMI
HEAT OBSERVING A MOMENT OF
VIOLENCE BEFORE YESTERDAY'S
GAME AND SOME OF THE HEATS
PLAYERS EVEN BROUGHT THEIR
CHILDREN TO STAND WITH THEM TO
HONOR THE VICTIMS OF THE
SENSELESS SEBRON
JAMES AND DWYANE WADE AMONG
THEM AND LEBRON WRITING THE
WORD NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT ON
HIS SNEAKERS.
UP NORTH, IN CANADA, THE
TORONTO RAPTORS STANDING IN
SILENCE BEFORE THEIR GAMES
AGAINST THE MAVERICKS AND THIS
REALLY WILL BE SCENE ACROSS
THE COUNTRY TODAY ASNAL GAMES
ALL HAVE A MOMENT OF SILENCE.
NOI SEVERAL TEAMS, INCLUDING
THE PATRIOTS, JETS, AND GIANTS
WILL ALL WEAR DECALS ON THEIR
HELMETS AND IN THE REGION,
AGAIN, PATRIOTS, GIANTS, JETS
WILL HAVE SPECIAL CEREMONIES
HONORING THE VICTIMS.
>> Alisyn: AND HEAD COACH, WE
SHOULD SAY, AND TAKE A LOOK AT
OUR CULTURE, HOW IT HAS
CHANGED AND MAYBE HOW IT'S TO
GET BACK TO FAITH INSTEAD OF
FEAR.
AND HOW WE DO THAT.
>> SUCH A WHO ARE REN DID DUST
THING HAS HAPPENED AND IT'S
IMPORTANT TO PUT IT IN THE
CONTEXT OF THEIR FAITH.
>> IT'S THE ONLY PLACE TO
TURN, TO LOVE.
♪
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
♪ OOH BABY,
CAN I DO FOR YOU TODAY? ♪
[ Female Announcer ] NEED HELP
KEEPING YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE?
ALIGN CAN HELP.
NLY ALIGN HAS BIFANTIS,
A PATENTED PROBIOTIC
THAT NATURALLY HELPS MAINTAIN
YOUR DIGESTIVE BALANCE.
TRY ALIGN TO HELP RETAIN
A BALANCED DIGESTIVE SYSTEM.
TRY THE #1 GASTROENTEROLOGIST
RECOMMENDED PROBIOTIC.
ALIGN.
>>  TOMORROW WILL BE THE FIRST
SCHOOL DAY, BACK TO SCHOOL
AFTER THE HORRIFIC SHOOTING IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT FOR MANY
KIDS AND EVEN THOSE WHO DID
NOT WITNESS THE TRAGEDY OR NOT
INVOLVED COULD STILL BE
TRAUMATIZED BY JUST HEARING
ABOUT IT.
HOW CAN WE AS PARENTS TALK TO
OUR KIDS AND HELP THEM COPE
WITH THIS.
TOM IS A PSYCHOTHERAPIST AND A
SCHOOL COUNSELOR, IT'S GREAT
TO HAVE YOU WITH US, TOM.
>> THANKS FOR HAVING ME.
I THINK MY PERSPECTIVE IS
UNIQUE CONSIDERING I WORK AS
PRIVATE PRACTICE AS THAT
THERAPIST IN A SCHOOL SYSTEM
AND I HAVE YOUNG CHILDREN IN
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> Alisyn: YOU'RE THE PERFECT
PERSON TO TALK TO.
LET'S BREAK IT DOWN BY AGE.
FOR KIDS WHO ARE UNDER EIGHT
YEARS OLD.
THAT'S MY KIDS AND DAVE'S
KIDS.
WHAT SHOULD WE TELL THEM.
>> KIDS UNDER EIGHT YOU NEED
TO INSULATE THEM FROM THE
PROBLEMS AND SOME PARENTS FEEL
THE NEED TO TALK TO THEIR
YOUNG KIDS ABOUT IT, BUT I'M
BIG ON MAINTAINING INNOCENCE,
ESPECIALLY THE YOUNG AGE AND
SO MANY THINGS THAT PARENTS
CAN DO.
JUST REALLY, REALLY BE AWARE
OF WHAT YOU'RE DEALING WITH
DURING THE COURSE OF THE DAY.
YOU HAVE THE TELEVISION ON AND
WATCHING CLIPS OF THE
CONNECTICUT SHOOTING.
TURN IT OFF.
>> Alisyn: SO YOU CAN INSULATE
THEM IF THEY'RE UNDER EIGHT
AND NEVER MENTION IT, THAT'S
WHAT YOU SHOULD DO.
IF THEY SOMEHOW SEE ON THE
NEWS REPORTS, THEN HOW DO YOU
TALK TO THEM.
>> IF THEY BRING IT UP TO YOU,
BUT YOU DON'T WANT TO OVERDO
IT WITH THEM AND DON'T WANT TO
INSTILL FEAR ON YOUNG KIDS WE
WANT OUR KIDS GOING BACK TO
SCHOOL.
>> Alisyn: AND ANSWER BRIEFLY.
>> AT THE SAME TIME RESPECT
THEIR EMOTIONS, OBVIOUSLY.
IF THEY WANT TO TALK ABOUT IT,
GO AHEAD AND TALK TO THEM
ABOUT IT.
>> Alisyn: IF YOUR CHILDREN
ARE EIGHT YEARS OLD THROUGH 12
YEARS OLD, IF THEY'RE
ADOLESCENTS?
>> THAT'S THE THING, YOU DON'T
WANT TO OVERDO, AND PROBABLY
TALK TO THEM AND INITIATE WITH
THEM AND SEE HOW THEY ARE
FEELING.
DON'T OVERDO AND TALK AS YOU
WOULD TO YOUR HUSBAND OR WIFE
ABOUT IT.
YOU WANT TO MAKE SURE THEY
FEEL SAFE NUMBER ONE, AND MAKE
SURE AS A PARENT YOUR OWN
ANXIETY.
WE FEEL THE ENERGY OF OTHERS
AROUND HUSBAND AND OUR KIDS
WILL FEEL OUR FEARS AND
ANXIETY AND OUR KIDS--
IF WE DON'T FEEL SAFE THEY'RE
NOT GOING TO FEEL SAVE.
>> Alisyn: SHOULD THEY SEE YOU
GRIEVING OR HAVE A STIFF UPPER
LIP.
>> YOU DON'T WANT TO SHED
TEARS AROUND THE HOUSE AND
CREATE AN ATMOSPHERE THAT'S
DOOM AND GLOOM.
TO SOME EXTENT.
DO IT ON YOUR OWN.
LEYOUR HUSBAND BE THE ONE
YOU'RE HUGGING.
>> Alisyn: AND 12 YEARS OLD
AND TEENAGERS?
>> 12 YEARS OLD, THESE KIDS
GET IT AND UNDERSTAND.
I THINK THIS IS AN OPPORTUNITY
NOW TO MAYBE TALK TO THEM
ABOUT IT TO SEE WHAT THEY'RE
FEELING, TO SEE WHAT THEIR
TAKE IS ON THIS PROBLEM AND I
THINK A COMPONENT, TOO, THROW
THE JOKES AROUND AND BE MATURE
AND DRIVE HOME THESE YOUNG
BUDDING ADOLESCENTS, THIS IS
SERIOUS STUFF AND NOT
SOMETHING TO BE TAKEN LIGHTLY
AND HAVE YOUR KIDS DO SOME
COMMUNITY SERVICE, YOU KNOW,
HAVE THEM TAKE AN OPPORTUNITY
TO HELP OUT.
AND YOU KNOW, MAKE A
DIFFERENCE IN THE WORLD.
>> THAT'S A GREAT ONE, A GREAT
ONE TO TURN THE GRIEF INTO
ACTION SOMEHOW AND SHOW THEM
THE WAY TO DO THAT.
>> WE'RE GOING TO SEE A LOT OF
SCHOOLS DOING THIS.
THE HIGH SCHOOL WHERE I WORK,
KIDS TO BE STEPPING UP TO THE
PLATE AND HOPEFULLY GOOD CAN
COME OUT THIS HAVE.
>> Alisyn: AND ONE OF THE
ISSUES WE RAISED IN THE LAST
SEGMENT, DAVE BRIGGS RAISED
THIS, SHOULD THE KIDS GO BACK
TO SANDY ELEMENTARY?
>> I WAS TALKING ABOUT THIS
RECENTLY, THE SCHOOLS ARE
GOING TO NEED TO GET CREATIVE.
THERE ARE KIDS THAT WILL NOT
BE ABLE TO ENTER THAT SCHOOL,
THEIR EMOTIONS ARE SHOT AND
MINDS, THEY'VE BEEN EXPOSED TO
THIS.
IT'S NOT GOING TO BE POSSIBLE
SO THE SCHOOL IS GOING TO HAVE
TO COME UP WITH SOME SORT
AFTER PLAN, YOU CAN'T TRY TO
FORCE THESE KIDS TO GO BACK TO
THE SCHOOL WHERE THEY WITNESS
ADD TRAUMATIC EXPERIENCE LIKE
THIS.
>> Alisyn: IN SITUATIONS LIKE
THIS, I THINK THAT SOMETIMES
THEY DO A NAME CHAEK OF THE
SCHOOL, SOMETIMES AN ENTIRE
VEN TU CHANGE, AS PTSD FOR
LACK AFTER BETTER WORD.
>> SUBSTANTIAL PTSD, NOT A
LIGHTLY TREADED POST TRAUMATIC
STRESS.
THIS IS LONG LASTING AND
DEEPLY EMBEDDED AND ELIMINATE
THE TRIGGER.
THE TRIGGER COULD BE
APPROACHING AND SEEING THE
BUILDING FOR MANY OF THE KIDS.
THEY'RE NOT GOING TO BE ABLE
TO ENTER THE BUILDING I'M SURE
THE OFFICIALS OR OTHER SCHOOL
OFFICIALS ARE ALREADY
DISCUSSING MEASURES HOW TO
HANDLE THIS.
>> Alisyn: AFTER A TRAUMA LIKE
THIS, HOW LONG SHOULD KIDS
TAKE OFF FROM SCHOOL.
>> NOT AN EVEN TO TAKE OFF.
WE'VE HAD HURRICANE SANDY, NOT
SURE IF THIS SCHOOL WILL MISS
A LOT OF SCHOOL DAYS, BUT THE
MOST IMPORTANT THING HERE I
THINK IS FAMILIES COMING
TOGETHER AND SCHOOLS SHOULD BE
SECONDARY.
GET THEM BACK WHEN THE TIME IS
RIGHT AND, YOU KNOW, FOCUS
MORE ON YOUR FAMILY AND BEING
TOGETHER AND EVERYBODY
DEALING.
>> Alisyn: AND TOM, YOU'RE A
SCHOOL COUNSELOR AND THANK YOU
FOR JOINING US.
>> THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
>> Alisyn: FAMILIES, A LOT OF
DIFFICULT ROAD AHEAD AS THEY
TRY TO COME TO GRIPS WITH THIS
TRAGEDY AND WE'RE BACK IN
NEWTOWN NEXT TALKING ABOUT THE
ROLE OF FAITH.
♪
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a
Droid Incredible 4G LTE
by HTC for $49.99.
Hurry in for a
Droid Incredible 4G LTE
YOU CAN'T ARGUE WITH
NUTRITION YOU CAN SEE.
GREAT GRAINS.
GREAT GRAINS CEREAL STARTS
WHOLE AND STAYS WHOLE.
SEE THE SEAM?
MORE PCESSED FLAKES LOOK
NOTHING LIKE NATURAL GRAINS.
I'M EATING WHAT I KN
IS BETTER NUTRITION.
MMMM. GREAT GRAINS.
SEARCH GREAT GRAINS
AND SEE FOR YOURSELF.
>>  WELCOME BACK TO "FOX &
FRIENDS" ON THIS SUNDAY
MORNING.
POPE BENEDICT XVI OFFERING HIS
PRAYERS DURING THIS TIME OF
TRAGEDY, SPEAKING EARLIER
TODAY IN VATICAN CITY.
>> I WAS DEEPLY SADDENED BY
THE SENSELESS VIOLENCE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, AND LOSS
OF CHILD AND CLOSENESS IN
PRAYER.
>> Dave: AND MORE DIFFICULT
DAYS AHEAD.
MOMENTS AGO RESIDENTS
GATHERING FOR SUNDAY MASS AT
ST. ROSE OF LIMA CATHOLIC
CHURCH.
>> Alisyn: AND FOX IS THERE
WITH MORE, HI, TODD.
>> Reporter:  GOOD MORNING,
SERVICES JUST LET OUT AND
ANOTHER SERVICE IS ABOUT TO
BEGIN.
AS THE PARISHIONERS WERE
LEAVING THE CHURCH BUILDING
THE BELLS WERE CHIMING, JESUS
WAS A FRIEND.
AND PEOPLE HERE TODAY, A VERY
SOMBER MOOD, BUT AT THE SAME
TIME PEOPLE ARE EMBRACING NOT
ONLY ONE ANOTHER, BUT THEIR
FAITH.
AND A FEW MOMENTS AGO, WE HAD
THE OPPORTUNITY TO TALK WITH A
MEMBER OF THE BILLY GRAHAM
EVANGELISTIC ASSOCIATION, THEY
HAVE A TEAM OF CHAPLAINS HERE,
AND HERE IS WHAT JACK MUNDY
HAD TO TELL US.
>> EMOTIONS ARE ALL OVER THE
MAP WITH FOLKS.
RANGES FROM ANGER, YOU NAME
IT, SHOCK, DENIAL, CAN'T
BELIEVE IT'S HAPPENED HERE,
HOW COULD SOMETHING LIKE THAT
HAPPEN IN A LITTLE COMMUNITY
LIKE THIS AND THOSE ARE THE
PEOPLE ASKED SUCH AS VIRGINIA
TECH, A QUIET COMMUNITY IN THE
SHCHANDOSHENANDOAH VALLEY.
IT'S NOT THE COMMUNITY, BUT
WHAT'S IN ONE'S HEART AND
CARRY OUT AN EVIL DEED.
>> THEIR MINISTRY TO THE FIRST
RESPONDERS, THOSE INDIVIDUALS
AT THE SCHOOL.
MANY OF THE CHAPLAINS ARE
RETIRED FIREFIGHTERS, AND
WE'RE BEING TOLD THEY'RE WELL
RECEIVED IN THIS COMMUNITY.
>> Kelly: AND TODD IS GIVING
US AN UPDATE ON WHAT'S GOING
ON IN TERMS OF THE CHURCH
ASPECT AND THE FAITH ASPECT,
WHICH IS SO VITAL.
AT A TIME WHEN SO MANY ARE
GRIPPED WITH FEAR, HOW DO YOU
FIND FAITH?
AND CERTAINLY THE CHAPLAINS ON
THE GROUND ARE HELPING THEM DO
THAT AS WELL AS THE MONSIGNORS
OF THE THE CATHOLIC CHURCHES
AND OTHER CHURCHES.
>> Alisyn: AND ALL DEVOTIONS
ARE WORKING OVERTIME.
HE'S ONE OF THE FEW PEOPLE WHO
ARE WORKING TO UNDERSTAND WHAT
HAPPENED IN NEWTOWN.
HE WAS IN COLUMBINE AND HIS
SISTER WAS KILLED.
CRAIG SCOTT JOINS US NEXT
HOUR.
♪
>>> A SAD MORNING, IT'S SUNDAY,
DECEMBER 16th.
WE'RE LEARNING THE NAMES AND
AGES OF THE LIVES CUT SHORT IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT AND HEARING
FROM THEIR FAMILIES.
>> MY DAUGHTER, EMILIE, WOULD BE
ONE OF THE FIRST ONES TO BE
STANDING AND GIVING HER LOVE AND
SUPPORT TO ALL THOSE VICTIMS.
BECAUSE THAT'S THE TYPE OF
PERSON THAT SHE IS.
>> WE HAVE MORE FROM THIS
REMARKABLE DAD AND HIS
INCREDIBLE MESSAGE OF
FORGIVENESS TODAY.
>>> THEN WILL WE EVER GET
ANSWERS, HOW AND WHY DID THIS
HAPPEN?
WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT WHERE
THE INVESTIGATION HEADS TODAY,
WE'RE GETTING A LIVE REPORT FROM
THE POLICE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> THIS PICTURE HAS BECOME THE
FACE OF THE TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN.
WE KNOW THIS WOMAN'S SISTER DIED
A HERO.
SHIELDING HER STUDENTS FROM THE
GUNMAN AND THE STORIES OF
BRAVERY DO NOT END THERE.
"FOX & FRIENDS" STARTS NOW.
>>> GOOD SUNDAY MORNING,
EVERYBODY.
I'M DAVE BRIGGS, ALISYN CAMEROTA
HERE WITH YOU TRYING TO PICK UP
THE PIECES AND TALK ABOUT THE
TRAGEDY IN WAYS AND TALK ABOUT
THE STORIES THAT DID INSPIRE
PEOPLE.
IT'S A DIFFICULT MORNING FOR
EVERYONE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
AND ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
THANKS FOR BEING HERE.
>> AS PRESIDENT OBAMA PREPARES
TO VISIT NEWTOWN THIS AFTERNOON
WE'RE LEARNING NEW DETAILS ABOUT
THE SUSPECT AND THE
INVESTIGATION INTO IF THERE IS A
POSSIBLE MOTIVE OR EXPLANATION
BEHIND THIS HORRIFYING CRIME.
>> PETER DOOCY JOINS US LIVE
FROM NEWTOWN WITH THE VERY
LATEST.
>> GOOD MORNING, DAVE.
A LOT OF FOLKS IN THE AREA HAVE
BEEN TAKING ADVANTAGE OF
COUNSELING PROVIDED AT A NEARBY
SCHOOL.
GRIEF COUNSELORS FROM NEW
ENGLAND DESCENDING ON THE AREA
TO HELP THESE PEOPLE HEAL BUT
IT'S DIFFICULT TO HEAL WHEN YOU
SEE THINGS LIKE THE SPREADSHEET
PROVIDED BY THE MEDICAL EXAMINER
YESTERDAY LISTING THE NAMES AND
THE BIRTH DATES OF EVERYONE WHO
DIED.
AND 16 OF THE VICTIMS WERE JUST
BORN IN 2006.
FOUR OF THEM WERE BORN IN 2005,
ONE GIRL, JOSEPHINE GAY TURNED
7, THE TUESDAY BEFORE SHE DIED
OF THE THE MEDICAL EXAMINER SAYS
EVERYONE WHO DIED WAS SHOT
BETWEEN 3 AND 11 TIMES WITH A
BUSH MASTER SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE
AND EVERY OTHER DETAIL THAT THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER SHARED MADE
THIS TERRIBLE CRIME EVEN HARDER
TO SWALLOW.
>> THERE WERE IN CUTE KID STUFF.
THEY WERE FIRST GRADERS WEARING
CUTE KID STUFF.
IT WAS THE KIND OF STUFF YOU
WOULD SEND YOUR KIDS OR
GRANDKIDS OUT THE DOOR TO FIRST
GRADE IN.
>> NOW, WE'RE HEARING THAT
THERE'S NO EVIDENCE THAT
AUTHORITIES HAVE BEEN ABLE TO
FIND OF ANY CONNECTION BETWEEN
ADAM LANZA OR HIS MOTHER TO GUN
CLUBS OR RANGES BUT FEDERAL
AGENTS WILL COME AND VISIT LOCAL
GUN RETAILERS AND SHOOTING
RANGES, TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHO
ADAM LANZA KNEW AND IF HE LEFT
CLUES BEFORE FRIDAY ABOUT WHAT
WAS ABOUT TO HAPPEN.
WE DID HEAR YESTERDAY FROM ADAM
LANZA'S AUNT, WHO EXPLAINED WHY
NANCY LANZA SHALL, THE MOTHER OF
THIS MASSACHUSETTS -- MASS
MURDERER KEPT SO MANY GUNS.
>> THEY WERE NOT A VIOLENT
FAMILY.
IF SHE HAD IT, IT WAS HAVE BEEN
FOR SELF-DEFENSE BECAUSE SHE DID
LIVE ALONE.
>> 26 CHRISTMAS TREES WERE
DONATED TODAY BY AN ANONYMOUS
PERSON IN NORTH CAROLINA.
THEY'RE BEING SET UP NOT FAR
AWAY FROM THE SCHOOL THIS
MORNING.
THAT'S AN EXAMPLE OF THE
NATIONAL SUPPORT FOR THE VICTIMS
OF THIS CRIME.
LOCALLY JUST ACROSS THE STREET,
YESTERDAY WE VISITED WITH A
GROUP OF STUDENTS FROM SANDY
HOOK WHO ESCAPED THE SCHOOL AND
YOU ARE LUCKY TO TO BE ALIVE.
THEY WERE HOLDING A YARD SALE
SELLING TOYS, THEIR OWN TOYS, TO
RAISE MONEY FOR THE AFFECTED
FAMILIES FOR CLASSMATES AND
NEIGHBORS.
THIS IS A TOWN THAT'S COMPLETELY
HEARTBROKEN AND IT'S TOUGH TO
TELL HOW LONG IT WILL TAKE FOR
PEOPLE TO FEEL BETTER BUT IT'S
GOING TO BE A VERY, VERY LONG
TIME.
BACK TO YOU.
>> PETER, JUST TO REPEAT THAT
POINT, YOU SAID THAT SURVIVORS,
THE KIDS, WERE SELLING THEIR OWN
TOYS TO TRY TO HELP THE FAMILIES
AFFECTED BY THIS?
>> THEY ARE.
WE ACTUALLY VISITED YESTERDAY --
WE WERE DRIVING BY AND SAW A
YARD SALE, TWO YOUNG KIDS THAT
LOOKED LIKE THE AGE OF SOME
SANDY HOOK STUDENTS.
WE STOPPED AND APPARENTLY -- WE
TALKED TO THE MOTHER AND SHE
SAID EVERY YEAR THEY TRY TO DO
SOMETHING FOR CHARITY WITH THE
PROCEEDS FROM YARD SALES, AN
ANNUAL FAMILY YARD SALE AND THEY
WERE GOING TO CALL IT OFF
SATURDAY BECAUSE THE WHOLE AREA
IS SO DEVASTATED.
YOU DRIVE AROUND AND YOU'LL SEE
A STATE TROOPER STATIONED
OUTSIDE SOMEONE'S HOUSE FOR
HOURS AT A TIME AND YOU KNOW
THAT MEANS THAT IS A HOUSE WHERE
A CHILD WHO DID NOT COME HOME
FROM SCHOOL ON FRIDAY LIVED.
AND THEN JUST A FEW STREETS
OVER, THESE KIDS DECIDED THAT
THEY CONVINCED THEIR MOM THEY
WANTED TO HAVE THE YARD SALE TO
SUPPORT THOSE FAMILIES OF THEIR
CLASSMATES.
AND THEY WERE OUT THERE SELLING
THEIR TOYS.
>> WOW.
>> PETER, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
ONE OF OUR VIEWERS, TERESA MACK
TWEETED SOME OF THE SITES, ONE
IS NEWTOWN MEMORIAL FUND.ORG.
I'LL PUT THAT ON TWITTER AS WELL
AND ALLISON WILL DO THE SAME ON
TWITTER.
>> THAT'S GREAT.
WE HAD THE SCHOOL COUNSELOR COME
ON, IF YOU MISSED IT, IN THE
LAST HOUR WHO SAID ONE OF THE
BEST WAYS TO GET YOUR KIDS
MOVING FORWARD IS TURN THEIR
GRIEF INTO ACTION AND HAVE THEM
DO COMMUNITY SERVICE.
>> THAT'S WHAT WE'RE SEEING.
THANK YOU FOR THAT REPORT.
IT BRINGS IT HOME.
THESE CHILDREN ARE STEPPING
FORWARD ALONG WITH THE SUPPORT
OF THEIR PARENTS AS WELL AS THE
COMMUNITY.
WHAT A TOUCHING THING TO DO FOR
YOUR COMMUNITY, SO THESE ARE
KIDS, 6, 7, AND PERHAPS OLDER,
REACHING OUT TO HELP THEIR
COMMUNITY AT A TIME LIKE THIS.
IT SHOWS THAT THERE'S A HEALING
PROCESS UNDER WAY.
WE ALSO HAVE SOUND FROM THE
FAMILIES AS WELL.
>> RIGHT, ROBBY PARKER, WHO IS
THE FATHER OF 6-YEAR-OLD EMILIE
PARKER, KILLED IN THE SHOOTING
ON FRIDAY.
HE SPOKE OUT ABOUT HIS DAUGHTER
ON SATURDAY AND SAID SOMETHING
THAT SURPRISED US AND MAY
SURPRISE ALL OF YOU.
HE STRUCK A TONE OF FORGIVENESS
EVEN FOR THE SHOOTER'S FAMILY.
LISTEN TO WHAT ROBBY PARKER HAD
TO SAY.
>> FIRST OF ALL I WOULD LIKE TO
OFFER OUR DEEPEST CONDOLENCES TO
ALL THE FAMILIES WHO WERE
DIRECTLY AFFECTED BY THIS
SHOOTING.
IT'S A HORRIFIC TRAGEDY AND OUR
HEARTS AND PRAYERS GO OUT TO
THEM.
THIS INCLUDES THE FAMILY OF THE
SHOOTER.
I CAN'T IMAGINE HOW HARD THIS
EXPERIENCE MUST BE FOR YOU.
I WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT OUR
FAMILY AND OUR LOVE AND SUPPORT
GO OUT TO YOU.
MY DAUGHTER, EMILIE, WOULD BE
ONE OF THE FIRST ONES TO BE
STANDING AND GIVING HER LOVE AND
SUPPORT TO ALL THOSE VICTIMS
BECAUSE THAT'S THE TYPE OF
PERSON THAT SHE IS.
NOT BECAUSE OF ANY PARENTING
THAT MY WIFE AND I COULD HAVE
DONE BUT BECAUSE THOSE ARE THE
GIFTS GIVEN TO HER BY HER
HEAVENLY FATHER.
>> A PICTURE "THE ASSOCIATED
PRESS" HAS FROM THE EMILIE
PARKER FUND Facebook PAGE
MIGHT TELL YOU PARENTS A STORY,
IF YOU CAN TAKE THIS PICTURE
HERE ON MY iPAD ON CAMERA 3.
THAT'S ON THE Facebook PAGE
FOR THE EMILIE PARKER MEMORIAL
FUND.
THAT'S JUST A BEAUTIFUL YOUNG
GIRL.
PROBABLY REMINDS MANY OF YOU OF
YOUR OWN KIDS.
>> YOU CAN'T BELIEVE HOW LITTLE
THEY ARE UNTIL YOU SEE A PICTURE
AND SEE THEIR AGES AND HEAR THE
VOICES OF THE KIDS WHO SURVIVED.
ANOTHER FAMILY, THAT OF GRACE
McDONALD, SHE'S 7 AND THEY
DIDN'T WANT TO MAKE A VERBAL
STATEMENT BUT THEY DID WRITE A
STATEMENT THEY WANTED EVERYONE
TO READ.
QUOTE, WE'RE OVERWHELMED BY THE
OUTPOURING OF LOVE AND SUPPORT
FROM SO MANY PEOPLE.
X-RAYS WAS THE LOVE AND LIGHT OF
OUR FAMILY.
WORDS CANNOT EXPRESS OUR SENSE
OF LOSS AND IT'S SIGNED BY LYNN
AND CHRIS AND HER PARENTS, AND
HER 11-YEAR-OLD BROTHER.
>> FOR THE VIGIL OF VICTORIA
SOTO, ONE OF THE TEACHERS.
STATEMENTS WERE MADE ABOUT HER
HEROISM AND HOW MUCH SHE LOVED
HER STUDENTS AND EVEN SACRIFICED
HER OWN LIFE FOR HER STUDENTS BY
SHIELDING THEM FROM THE GUNMAN
AFTER SHE WAS CONFRONTED.
APPARENTLY SHE HEARD WHAT WAS
GOING ON.
THERE ARE REPORTS SHE PERHAPS
HID THE CHILDREN IN A CUPBOARD
AND WHEN THE GUNMAN CONFRONTED
HER, SHE TOLD HIM THEY WERE NOT
THERE.
THERE ARE OTHER REPORTS SHE SAW
HIM AND SHIELDED THE CHILDREN.
INCREDIBLE MOMENTS OF HEROISM.
YOU LOOK AT ROBBY PARKER AND
THAT CAPACITY TO FORGIVE, HAVING
COMPASSION ON THE KILLER AND HIS
FAMILY AT A TIME WHEN HE'S
GRIEVING FOR THE LOSS OF HIS OWN
DAUGHTER.
>> I THINK A LOT OF PEOPLE,
THEIR INITIAL REACTION IS SO
BLAME THE PARENTS AND SAY HOW
DID THEY MISS THE WARNING SIGNS
AND ALLOW ACCESS TO WEAPONS TO A
YOUNG KID WHO IS CLEARLY
TROUBLED.
TO HAVE FORGIVENESS IS
UNMANAGEABLE TO ME, BUT
ADMIRABLE.
ROBBY PARKER SHARED THE LAST
MEMORIES HE HAD WITH HIS
6-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER.
>> SHE WOKE UP BEFORE I LEFT AND
I HAD BEEN TEACHING HER
PORTUGUESE, SO HER LAST
CONVERSATION WAS IN PORTUGUESE
AND SHE -- SHE TOLD ME GOOD
MORNING AND ASKED HOW I WAS
DOING.
I SAID I WAS DOING WELL.
SHE SAID THAT SHE LOVED ME AND I
GAVE HER A KISS AND I WAS OUT
THE DOOR.
>> IT'S WONDERFUL TO HEAR FROM
HIM.
HE'S AN INSPIRATION OBVIOUSLY.
DAVE, YOU'RE RIGHT, PARTICULARLY
AT THIS HOUR, TO HAVE
FORGIVENESS.
A LOT OF PEOPLE WORK AROUND TO
IT WITH A BIG HEART AND MAGNANMY
BUT FOR HIM TO HAVE IT IN 24
HOURS IS INCREDIBLE.
HE'S ONE OF THE FEW PEOPLE THAT
UNDERSTAND WHAT IS HAPPENING AND
HOW THEY'RE FEELING IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
HE SURVIVED COLUMBINE AND HIS
SISTER WAS KILLED.
YOU WILL PROBABLY REMEMBER CRAIG
SCOTT'S FACE.
HE'S GOING TO JOIN US TO TALK
NOW.
initiated.
Neural speeds
increasing to 4G LTE.
Brain upgrading to a quad-core
processor.
Predictive intelligence
with Google Now complete.
Introducing DROID DNA by HTC.
It's not an upgrade
to your phone.
It's an upgrade to yourself.
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
>>> PUBLIC POLICY SURROUNDING
YESTERDAY'S EVENT.
WHAT IS IMPORTANT RIGHT NOW IS
LOVE, COURAGE, AND COMPASSION.
>> THAT WAS CONNECTICUT GORDAN
MALLOY REACTING TO FRIDAY'S
TRAGIC SHOOTING.
IT WILL BE A DIFFICULT HEALING
PROTEST FOR THE FAMILIES OF THE
SHOOTING VICTIMS IN NEWTOWN.
SOMEONE WHO KNOWS THIS PAIN TOO
WELL JOINS US.
CRAIG SCOTT'S SISTER, RACHEL,
WAS THE FIRST KILLED IN THE
MASSACRE IN COLORADO AND HE WAS
IN THE SCHOOL LIBRARY DURING
THAT RAMPAGE.
THANKS FOR BEING WITH US THIS
MORNING.
>> THANK YOU.
>> I REMEMBER YOUR STORY
VIVIDLY.
THE WHOLE COUNTRY DOES.
YOU WERE A YOUNG MAN IN THOSE
HOURS AFTER COLUMBINE AND YOU
SPOKE OUT SO COMPELLINGLY AND
COMPASSIONATELY AND POIGNANTLY
AND I CAN ONLY IMAGINE NOW HOW
MORE REPORTS OF SCHOOL MASSACRES
LIKE THIS AFFECT YOU.
WHAT HAPPENED ON FRIDAY WHEN YOU
HEARD THE NEWS?
>> LIKE EVERYONE, JUST EXTREME
SADNESS AND BROKENHEARTED.
I KNEW THAT I ESPECIALLY FELT
FOR PARENTS WHO LOST THEIR
CHILDREN AND HOW DEVASTATED THEY
WERE GOING TO BE.
ALSO IT JUST -- IT ALSO JUST
MADE ME THINK ABOUT KIND OF
WHERE MY GENERATION IS AS FAR AS
WHAT OUR VALUES ARE AND EVEN THE
SPIRITUAL CONDITION OF OUR
GENERATION.
BECAUSE I LOOK AT THE LAST FEW
SHOOTINGS THAT HAPPENED ALL FROM
GUYS IN THEIR 20s, AND IT MADE
ME ANGRY.
>> CRAIG, I WAS THERE FOR THE
WEEKS THAT FOLLOWED AT COLUMBINE
AS WELL BEING FROM DENVER, I
UNFORTUNATELY COVERED THAT.
I'M CURIOUS ABOUT WHAT YOU SAID
ABOUT YOUR GENERATION AND
VALUES.
WHAT NEEDS TO CHANGE?
WHAT IS YOUR MESSAGE TO PEOPLE
IN THEIR LATE TEENS, EARLY
20s?
WHAT DOES NEED TO CHANGE IN
TERMS OF PRIORITIES AND VALUES
TODAY?
>> EVERY WEEK I'M ALL ACROSS THE
COUNTRY SPENDING TIME WITH
TEENAGERS AND PEOPLE IN THEIR
20s AT COLLEGES.
AND I THINK THAT WE -- AS A
GENERATION, HAVE TO ASK
OURSELVES AS AMERICANS WHAT DO
WE STAND FOR, WHAT DO WE BELIEVE
IN?
BECAUSE THERE'S A WAR CULTURALLY
IN OUR HEARTS GOING ON TODAY I
THINK.
THERE'S A LOT OF DARK THINGS
THAT I THINK THESE SHOOTERS AND
OTHER PEOPLE ARE TAPPING INTO.
SO MUCH VIOLENCE THROUGH THE
MEDIA AND DARK STUFF OVER THE
INTERNET THAT THEY'RE INFLUENCED
BY LIVING THAT ONLINE LIFESTYLE.
I JUST THINK WHERE IS THE
RESPECT FOR LIFE, THE SANCTITY
OF LIFE?
I KNOW THAT WHEN I TRAVEL AROUND
AND MEET SO MANY TEENAGERS THAT
WHETHER IT'S AT HOME OR AT
SCHOOL, THEY'RE NOT -- THEY'RE
NOT GROWING UP IN A CULTURE
WHERE THEY LEARN ABOUT WHAT ARE
THE VALUES THAT THEY'RE GOING TO
HOLD ONTO THAT ARE IMPORTANT.
AND I THINK ABOUT THIS -- MY
FATHER'S GENERATION, I KNOW THAT
NO ONE IN HIS GENERATION WOULD
HAVE DREAMED OF GOING INTO A
KINDERGARTEN CLASS AND KILLING
EVERY KINDERGARTENER UNLESS THEY
WERE ABSOLUTELY CRAZY.
THESE AREN'T CRAZY PEOPLE.
THEY'RE -- THEY CAN THINK AND
RATIONALIZE LOGICALLY, WEATHER
THE SHOOTING AT THE THEATER OR
THIS ONE THAT HAPPENED.
SO I THINK THAT WHEN YOU HAVE A
CULTURE WHERE, IF MY GENERATION
EMBRACES CERTAIN VALUES AND
THINGS SPIRITUALLY, IT'S GOING
TO BE LIKE A LIGHT AND -- AND
THERE'S A LOT OF DARKNESS RIGHT
NOW AND -- IN OUR CULTURE, IN
OUR GENERATION.
THOSE ARE SYMPTOM OF THE
I THINK -- SOME OF THE THINGS I
THINK ABOUT.
>> WE TALKED TO YOUR MOM
YESTERDAY.
SHE'S SO INSPIRATIONAL.
SHE SAID THE PARENTS WILL SOME
DAY, SOMEHOW, GET PAST THEIR
GRIEF.
SHE TALKED ABOUT IT WILL TAKE A
LONG TIME BUT SOME DAY YOU WILL
BE ABLE TO SMILE AGAIN.
ONE THING SHE SAID THAT STUCK
WITH ME IS SHE THOUGHT YOU WERE
GOING TO BE A CASUALTY TOO.
NOT LITERALLY BUT FIGURATIVELY.
THERE WERE TWO YEARS THAT YOU
WERE SO GRIEF-STRICKEN THAT SHE
THOUGHT YOU WERE LOST.
HOW DID YOU TURN IT AROUND
PERSONALLY?
>> I WENT THROUGH A LOT OF
DEPRESSION AND ANGER AFTER THE
SHOOTING.
I HATED THE TWO SHOOTERS.
I USED TO CARRY THAT ANGER WITH
ME, ANYTIME SOMEONE TALKED ABOUT
THEM OR THOUGHT ABOUT THEM, IT
WAS LIKE A BLACK CLOUD ENVELOPED
ME AND I STARTED TO TAKE IT OUT
ON PEOPLE I WAS CLOSE WITH.
AND IT TOOK TIME, BUT I
EVENTUALLY FOUND THAT THE WAY TO
NOT HOLD ON TO THAT WAS TO
FORGIVE AND LET GO.
AND A LOT OF TIMES PEOPLE DON'T
UNDERSTAND FORGIVENESS AND
THINKING IT'S SAYING WHAT
SOMEONE DID IS OKAY.
IT WASN'T THAT.
IT WAS LETTING GO OF THE RIGHT
TO HATE.
I JUST KNEW THAT FOR ME, I
DIDN'T WANT TO BE A BITTER
PERSON DOWN THE ROAD.
AND I THINK THAT WITH THE PEOPLE
IN THIS COMMUNITY, WHO HAVE A
RIGHT TO BE ANGRY AT WHAT HAS
HAPPENED, THAT THEY WILL THINK
ABOUT WHO THEY WANT TO BE DOWN
THE ROAD AND WHAT THEY'RE GOING
TO CHOOSE TO FOCUS ON.
MY -- SOME OF THE THINGS THAT
HELPED ME WAS STICKING TOGETHER
WITH MY FAMILY AND MY FAITH.
IT REALLY HELPED ME HEAL
MENTALLY AND SPIRITUALLY.
>> YOU TALKED ABOUT THE SPEAKING
YOU AND YOUR FAMILY DO AROUND
THE COUNTRY, RACHEL'S CHALLENGE,
WHICH TRAVELS TO SCHOOLS TO
EDUCATE PARENTS AND KIDS.
YOU TALK ABOUT THE CODE OF
ETHICS THAT YOUR SISTER WROTE
BEFORE SHE WAS KILLED.
NOT MANY HIGH SCHOOLERS WRITE A
CODE OF ETHICS.
WHAT IS THE MESSAGE THAT YOUR
SISTER WOULD WANT YOU TO
CONTINUE PREACHING ACROSS THE
COUNTRY?
>> WELL HER MESSAGE WAS TO STEP
OUT OF YOUR WAY IN COMPASSION
FOR OTHER PEOPLE, TO SHOW
KINDNESS AND START A CHAIN
REACTION OF KINDNESS AND
COMPASSION.
SHE WENT OUT OF HER WAY FOR
PEOPLE THAT WERE ON THE OUTSIDE,
PEOPLE THAT WERE HURTING.
SHE HAD A HEART FOR THESE
PEOPLE.
THAT'S THE SAME CHALLENGE WE
GIVE TO TEENS AND COLLEGES AND
EVEN ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS ACROSS
THE COUNTRY.
WE SEE STUDENTS ACCEPT THAT
CHALLENGE AS THEY HEAR ABOUT A
TEENAGER AND WE PRESENT TO THEM
A ROLE MODEL OF SOMEONE WHO
BELIEVED THAT SHE COULD MAKE A
DIFFERENCE THROUGH SIMPLE ACTS
OF KINDNESS AND FEELING FOR
OTHER PEOPLE.
>> WELL, CRAIG SCOTT, YOUR
SISTER AND YOU HAVE BEEN REAL
LIGHTS IN THE DARKNESS OF THESE
TERRIBLE TRAGEDIES.
IT'S WONDERFUL TO SPEAK TO YOU.
THANKS FOR BRINGING YOUR
INSPIRATIONAL MESSAGE.
>> THANK YOU.
>> WE'LL TELL YOU WHERE TO FIND
MORE INFORMATION ON RACHEL'S
CHALLENGE O.J. ON LINE.
-- ON LINE.
WHAT COULD HAVE PROMPTED HIM TO
CARRY OUT THAT ATTACK?
QUESTIONS ALL THROUGHOUT SOCIETY
WE'LL EXPLORE NEXT.
have a knack
for giving the perfect gift?
They put real thought into it.
And find just...
the right...thing.
How do they do that?
More saving. More doing.
That's the power of The
Home Depot.
Pick up a RIDGID JobMax
multi-tool starter kit and
get a free head attachment.
>>> WHEN THE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS
SCHOOL SHOOTING STRIKE MANY ARE
LEFT TO WONDER WHY IT HAPPENED
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
OUR NEXT GUEST SAYS IT'S THE
CULTURE IN AMERICA.
>> JOINING US, JAMES HEARSTEN.
HI, JAMES.
>> GOOD MORNING.
>> I DON'T HAVE TO TELL YOU THE
UNITED STATES HAS HAD MORE
SCHOOL SHOOTINGS THAN ANY OTHER
COUNTRY IN THE WORLD.
WHAT'S GOING ON IN OUR CULTURE?
>> OUR CONSULT, PARTICULARLY OUR
POP CONSULT, IS EXTREMELY
VIOLENT.
JUST RECENTLY JAMIE FOXX WHO
SPOKE OUT, HOE HAS A VIOLENT
MOVIE COMING OUT, THAT HOLLYWOOD
BEARS A RESPONSIBILITY WITH
THESE KINDS OF EVENTS.
I THINK WHAT WE HAVE TO LOOK AT
IS A WHOLE HOST OF MEDIA BUT
PARTICULARLY VIDEO GAMES.
BECAUSE VIDEO GAMES ARE
INTERACTIVE, VIDEO GAMES INVOLVE
ALL THE SENSES OF THE MODALITIES
OF LEARNING AND THERE'S BEEN A
RECENT STUDY OUT OF AUSTRALIA
THAT SHOWS VIDEO GAMES ARE
ADDICTIVE AND THERE ARE SOCIAL
CONSEQUENCES TO IT IS ADDICTION.
THEY GET INTO A STATE OF
ISOLATION THAT FEEDS THE
ADDICTION, THEY RETREAT INTO AN
ONLINE WORLD.
AND TECHNOLOGY HAS NOW MADE
VIDEO GAME VIOLENCE MORE
COMPELLING BECAUSE IT'S
REALISTIC AND PEOPLE ARE
DESIGNING THESE GAMES TO
LITERALLY TEACH THE PLAYERS HOW
TO MAIM, HOW TO MURDER, WITH
GREAT BRUTALITY AND SADISM.
THE PROBLEM IS PARENTS ARE
SOMETIMES UNAWARE OF THE
DELIVERY SYSTEMS WITH THE NEW
TECHNOLOGY AND UNAWARE OF THE
CONTENT OF THIS MATERIAL.
SO IT'S A GREAT CONCERN.
BUT THE MEDIA AS A WHOLE IS
POLLUTED WITH THIS KIND OF
GRATUITOUS, EXPLICIT, DETAILED,
GRAPHIC VIOLENCE.
>> WE WERE TALKING EARLIER IN
THE SHOW AND DISCUSSED THE FACT
THERE ARE SOME MEASURES IN
PLACE, FOR EXAMPLE, WARNING
LABELS ABOUT THE GRAPHIC NATURE
OF THE VIOLENCE AND PARENTS
SHOULD ACTUALLY MONITOR THEIR
CHILDREN.
IS IT IMPORTANT AT THIS POINT TO
DRIVE THAT HOME TO PARENTS THAT
THEY SHOULD BE AWARE OF WHAT
THEIR CHILDREN MIGHT BE GETTING
INVOLVED IN WITH THE VIDEO GAME
OR WATCHING ON TELEVISION?
>> IT IS MORE CRITICAL THAN EVER
IN OUR TIME WITH THIS TECHNOLOGY
THAT PARENTS ARE INFORMED AND
THAT THEY'RE INVOLVED.
AS YOU POINT OUT, THERE ARE
WONDERFUL RATINGS AVAILABLE, THE
ENTERTAINMENT SOFTWARE RATINGS
BOARD FOR VIDEO GAMES IS A
NONPROFIT, SELF-REGULATORY BODY
THAT RATES THESE.
THE VIOLENCE IS PREVALENT IN
LYRICS TO SONGS.
IT'S PREVALENT ON TELEVISION.
IT'S PREVALENT IN THE MOVIES AND
VIDEO GAMES AND THEY ALL HAVE
DIFFERENT RATING SYSTEMS.
IT WILL REALLY HELP IF THERE
WERE A UNIFORM RATING SYSTEM
THAT WAS SIMPLE, CLEAR, AND EASY
TO UNDERSTAND FOR PARENTS AND
CHILDREN.
HARVEY WEINSTEIN RECENTLY CALLED
FOR A SUMMIT ON VIOLENCE IN THE
AFTERMATH OF THE LITTLETON
THEATER SHOOTING.
IT'S TIME FOR A SUMMIT WHERE ALL
MEDIA PARTICIPANTS TAKE PART,
THAT PEOPLE INVOLVED IN THE
MUSIC INDUSTRY, MUSIC INDUSTRY,
TELEVISION INDUSTRY, VIDEO GAME
INDUSTRY, GET TOGETHER AND THEY
COME UP WITH A CLEAR
UNDERSTANDABLE RATING SYSTEM
THAT HELPS PARENTS IN THIS
CRITICAL TIME.
>> JAMES HEARSTEN, YOU'VE MADE A
CONVINCING CASE THIS MORNING
ABOUT ONE OF THE THINGS THAT'S
WRONG IN OUR CULTURE.
THANKS SO MUCH.
>> IT'S MY PLEASURE, THANKS FOR
HAVING ME.
>> SOMETHING WE'VE BEEN TALKING
ABOUT.
NEXT, A LIVE UPDATE FROM
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE.
WE'RE LEARNING NEW DETAILS ABOUT
THE INVESTIGATION.
AMID THE DEVASTATING TRAGEDY,
THIS PICTURE LEAVING AN
INDELIBLE IMAGE AS OUR NATION
MOURNS.
NOW WE KNOW THIS WOMAN'S SISTER
DIED A HERO, SHIELDING HER
STUDENTS FROM THE GUNMAN AND THE
STORIES OF BRAVERY DO NOT END
THERE.
>>> BEHIND EVERY ONE OF THOSE
NAMES AND AGES, A FAMILY THAT
DESPERATELY LOVED ALL THOSE KIDS
AND ADULTS YOU SAW THERE.
IT DRIVES HOME THE TRAGEDY OF
ALL THIS WHEN YOU SEE THE AGES
NEXT TO THEIR NAMES.
MANY VICTIMS ARE TURNING TO
FAITH TODAY FOR COMFORT.
>> IN FRONT OF THE ST. ROSE OF
LIMA CHURCH IN CONNECTICUT WHERE
HUNDREDS HAVE BEEN ATTENDING
SERVICES AND ANOTHER ONE IT
TAKING PLACE THIS MORNING.
GOOD MORNING, ANNA.
>> GOOD MORNING, TO YOU AND GOOD
MORNING TO EVERYBODY AT HOME.
THROUGH THE NEWTOWN COMMUNITY
MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS ARE POPPING
UP.
MANY SAY PRAY FOR SANDY HOOK
CHURCH SERVICES.
MANY ARE MEMORIAL SERVICES
HONORING 20 INNOCENT CHILDREN
AND SIX ADULTS WHO LOST THEIR
LIVES FRIDAY.
MANY RESIDENTS FEEL AS IF THEY
HAVE NO WAY TO HELP THE FAMILIES
EXCEPT THROUGH FAITH AND PRAYER.
>> IT'S AN UNIMAGINABLE LOSS.
THERE'S NO WORDS TO DESCRIBE IT.
THERE'S NOTHING YOU CAN SAY TO
CONSOLE THEM.
PART OF THEM IS LOST FOREVER.
>> LAST NIGHT HUNDREDS GATHERED
FOR WHAT IS NORMALLY A SATURDAY
NIGHT CHILDREN'S SERVICE AT
ST. ROSE OF LIMA CHURCH.
SOME PARENTS WHO LOST THEIR
CHILDREN MOURNING WITH NEIGHBORS
TAKING A BREAK FROM PLANNING
FUNERALS.
AFTER STANDING ROOM ONLY
SERVICE, SOME SCHOOL AGE
CHILDREN PUT ON A LIVING
NATIVITY SCENE REMINDING
RESIDENTS LIFE GOES ON.
>> I PRAY GOD WILL HEAL THESE
PEOPLE.
WE HAVE TWO YOUNG DAUGHTERS AND
I CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT IT MUST
FEEL LIKE.
>> PEOPLE ACROSS THE COUNTRY ARE
TRYING TO MAKE SENSE OF THE
TRAGEDY.
THE OAK CREEK WISCONSIN
COMMUNITY THAT LOST A HALF DOZEN
WORSHIPPERS IN A TEMPLE SHOOTING
HELD A SERVICE REMEMBERING WHAT
THEY WENT THROUGH IN AUGUST AND
LIVING UP PRAYER FOR
CONNECTICUT.
PRESIDENT BARACK OBAMA IS
SCHEDULED TO VISIT THE SANDY
HOOK COMMUNITY TODAY, THE FOURTH
TIME HE'S VISITED A TOWN IN
MORNING FOLLOWING A MASS
SHOOTING.
>> THANK YOU.
OVER IN ITALY, AT VATICAN CITY,
THE POPE TALKED ABOUT THIS AS
WELL, PAYING SPECIAL HONOR THAT
IN HIS HOMILY IN THE MASSES AT
THE VATICAN EXPRESSING HIS
SADNESS AND REGRET.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT A SITUATION
LIKE THIS, WE'RE TRYING TO FIND
ANSWERS AND WE DON'T HAVE
ANSWERS.
POLICE ARE TRYING TO PUT
EVERYTHING TOGETHER BUT THERE
WERE HEROIC TEACHERS WHO ACTED
SO BRAVELY TO SAVE THE LIVES OF
THEIR STUDENTS.
SO MANY OF THEM COMING THEIR
RESCUE.
>> VICTORIA SOTO PROBABLY ONE OF
OF THE BEST STORIES TO EMERGE
OUT OF THE HORROR THERE AT SAND
HOOK.
SHE WAS 27 YEARS OLD, A
DEDICATED YOUNG TEACHER, A
BEAUTIFUL YOUNG GWHAT SHE APPARK
ALL OF THE STUDENTS AND -- THESE
DETAILS ARE STILL EMERGING.
FROM WHAT IT APPEARS SHE TOLD
HER STUDENTS TO GO IN CUBBIES OR
CABINETS AND WENT THE SHOOTER
APPROACHED HER, SHE TOLD THE
SHOOTER HER STUDENTS WERE GONE
TO THE GYM OR LIBRARY AND PAID
FOR IT WITH HER LIFE BUT
PROTECTED THE ENTIRE CLASS.
>> EVEN PEOPLE WHO DON'T KNOW
HER HEARD THE STORY OF HOW HER
FIRST GRADERS WERE ABLE TO
SURVIVE SO AT A VIGIL, PEOPLE
WERE TALKING ABOUT HER.
>> I DIDN'T KNOW HER AT ALL, BUT
I'M A MOM MYSELF.
AND IT COULD HAVE BEEN MY KID.
WHAT SHE DID IS VERY BRAVE.
I RESPECT HER.
>> THE PAIN, HOW THOSE MOTHERS
MUST BE FEELING AT THIS TIME,
BECAUSE THIS IS MY ONLY CHILD
AND I COULDN'T PICTURE THAT.
THAT'S WHY I'M HERE TODAY,
BECAUSE SHE SAVED A LOT OF KIDS'
LIVES.
>> I HOPE ONE DAY HE'LL KNOW
SHE'S IN A BETTER PLACE AND SHE
DIED A HERO.
>> THERE'S ALSO AN ICONIC
PHOTOGRAPH THAT CAUGHT THE
ATTENTION OF THE COUNTRY.
A GRIEF-STRICKEN YOUNG WOMAN, WE
NOW KNOW THIS IS JILLIAN SOTO,
THE SISTER OF VICKY, WHO WE
ASSUME IS RECEIVING THE NEWS OF
HER SISTER'S FATE.
>> THEY HAD A VIGIL LAST NIGHT.
WE HAD HAD PRINCIPAL AND SCHOOL
PSYCHIATRIST THAT WENT AFTER --
OR CONFRONTED THE SHOOTER.
THEY GAVE THEIR OWN LIVES AS
WELL.
>> WE DO HAVE A LITTLE BIT OF
OTHER NEWS.
LET'S GET TO THE HEADLINES.
ON THE DAY OF THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL MASSACRE POLICE IN
OKLAHOMA STOPPED ANOTHER
MASSACRE WERE HAPPENING.
18-YEAR-OLD SAMMY CHAVEZ WAS
ARRESTED FRIDAY.
HE WAS RECRUITING CLASSMATES TO
LURE OTHER STUDENTS INTO THE
AUDITORIUM WHERE HE PLANNED TO
CHAIN THE DOORS AND OPEN FIRE.
HE ALSO WANTED TO PUT BOMBS AT
THE DOORS TO GO OFF WHEN POLICE
ARRIVED.
ANOTHER STUDENT ALERTED POLICE
ABOUT THE PLOT.
>> YOU COULD BE LOOKING AT THE
NEW SECRETARY OF STATE.
FOXFOX PRESIDENT OBAMA IS EXPECD
TO NOMINATE JOHN KERRY FOR THE
JOB.
HE WOULD REPLACE HILLARY
CLINTON.
WHILE YOU WERE SLEEPING, NOW
PROGRESS IN WASHINGTON ON
AVOIDING THE FISCAL CLIFF.
FOX NEWS LEARNED SPEAKER BOEHNER
HAS PROPOSED A TAX INCREASE FOR
PEOPLE MAKING $1 MILLION A YEAR
OR ABOVE.
HE PREVIOUSLY STOOD FAST ON THE
ISSUE UNLESS THERE WAS
COMPROMISE.
>> WASHINGTON HAS A SPENDING
PROBLEM.
THEY CAN'T BE FIXED WITH TAX
INCREASES ALONE.
THE PRESIDENT WILL STEP UP AND
SHOW US HE'S WILLING TO MAKE
SPENDING CUTS THAT ARE NEEDED, I
THINK WE CAN DO REAL GOOD IN THE
DAYS AHEAD.
>> SO FAR, NO RESPONSE FROM THE
WHITE HOUSE TO THIS OFFER.
>>> THE TRAGEDY OF NEWTOWN IS OF
COURSE MOURNED BY PEOPLE ACROSS
THE COUNTRY, ACROSS THE WORLD,
FROM TIMES SQUARE IN NEW YORK
CITY, PEOPLE HOLDING CANDLES AND
SIGNS.
TO PEOPLE IN LOS ANGELES,
PRAYING BY CANDLELIGHT, LINING
THE BEACH IN RIO DE JANEIRO WITH
MOURNERS LYING FLOWERS IN THE
SAND.
IN PAKISTAN, CHILDREN SENDING
MESSAGES OF COMPASSION, LIGHTING
CANDLES ON THE STREETS IN
TRIBUTE.
IT'S REMINISCENT OF 9/11.
>> WOW.
WHEN YOU GET THAT KIND OF
REACTION GLOBALLY, IT
UNDERSCORES THE PAIN WE'RE
FEELING HERE BUT HOW THE WORLD
FOCUSES ON WHAT'S HAPPENING HERE
IN AMERICA.
WE'VE GOT TO ASK THE QUESTION,
WHAT'S GOING ON?
>> A LOT OF CONVERSATIONS YET TO
COME.
WATCH "FOX NEWS CHANNEL"
TONIGHT, 6:00 EASTERN, WHERE
BRET BAIER WILL BRING SPECIAL
COVERAGE OF THE PRESIDENT'S
VISIT TO NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
ED HENRY IS TRAVELING WITH THE
PRESIDENT AND WE'LL BRING YOU
THE LATEST FROM THERE.
>> NEXT, A LIVE UPDATE FROM
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE.
WE'RE LEARNING NEW DETAILS ABOUT
THE INVESTIGATION.
TO THE BEST VACATION
SPOT ON EARTH.
(ALL) THE GULF!
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHICH OF
OUR GREAT STATES FOLKS VISIT.
MISSISSIPPI,
ALABAM
LOUISIANA
OR FLORIDA,
THEY'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
SHAUL, YOUR ALABAMA
HOSPITALITY IS INCREDIBLE.
THANKS, KAREN.
LOVE YOUR MISSISSIPPI OUTDOORS.
I VOTE FOR YOUR
FLORIDA BEACHES, DAWN.
BILL, THIS LOUISIANA
SEAFOOD IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR ON THE GULF,
WE'VE DECIDED TO PUT
ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
NOW IS THE PERFECT TIME TO
VISIT ANYONE OF OUR STATES.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE, GO FISHING
OR JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
WE'VE GOT COASTLINE TO EXPLORE
AND WILDLIFE TO PHOTOGRAPH.
AND THERE'S WORLD CLASS DINING
WITH OUR WORLD FAMOUS SEAFOOD.
SO FOR A GREAT VACATION
THIS YEAR, COME TO THE GULF.
ITS ALL FABULOUS BUT
I GIVE FLORIDA THE EDGE.
RIGHT AFTER MISSISSIPPI.
YOU MEAN ALABAMA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
THIS INVITATION IS
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP
AND ALL OF US WHO
CALL THE GULF HOME.
AT LEGALZOOM, WE'VE CREATED
A BETTER PLACE
TO HANDLE YOUR LEGAL NEEDS.
MAYBE YOU HAVE QUESTIONS
ABOUT INCORPORATING
A BUSINESS
YOU'D LIKE TO START.
OR QUESTIONS
ABOUT PROTECTING YOUR FAMILY
WITH A WILL OR LIVING TRUST.
AND YOU'D LIKE TO FIND
THE RIGHT ATTORNEY
TO HELP GUIDE YOU ALONG,
ANSWER ANY QUESTIONS
AND OFFER ADVICE.
WITH AN "A" RATING FROM
THE BETTER BUSINESS BUREAU
LEGALZOOM HELPS YOU GET
PERSONALIZED AND AFFORDABLE
LEGAL PROTECTION.
IN MOST STATES, A LEGAL PLAN
ATTORNEY IS AVAILABLE WITH
EVERY PERSONALIZED DOCUMENT
TO ANSWER ANY QUESTIONS.
GET STARTED AT LEGALZOOM.COM
TODAY.
AND NOW YOU'RE PROTECTED.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO SUNDAY
MORNING.
IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE ONE OF THE
MOST JOYOUS TIMES OF THE YEAR
BUT FAMILIES IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT AND AROUND THE
COUNTRY ARE DEALING WITH THIS
TRAGEDY.
WITH CHRISTMAS ONE WEEK AWAY,
HOW DO YOU ARE HE STORE FAITH IN
GOD?
>> JOINING US, FATHER JOHNATHAN
MORRIS.
GREAT TO HAVE YOU HERE.
HAVE YOU BEEN IN TOUCH WITH
PEOPLE IN NEWTOWN?
>> I HAVE.
I'M NOT GOING TODAY BECAUSE I
HAVE MY SERVICES IN NEW YORK
CITY.
BUT WHEN THINGS CALM DOWN, WHEN
THE SHOCK BEGINS TO WEAR OFF
THAT'S WHEN MORE SUPPORT,
FRIENDSHIP, CLOSENESS NEEDS TO
BE THERE.
I AND SO MANY OTHERS WILL BE
THERE.
>> WE TALKED ABOUT OUR REACTION
TO ROBBY PARKER, THE FATHER OF
YOUNG 6-YEAR-OLD EMILIE PARKER,
WHO WAS HIS OLDEST DAUGHTER, HE
HAS THREE.
WE CERTAINLY UNDERSTAND HIM
REACHING OUT TO THE COMMUNITY,
BUT HE ALSO WENT SO FAR AS TO
FORGIVE.
EXPLAIN TO ME AND ALL OF US WHY
FORGIVENESS IS SO ESSENTIAL AND
WHAT IT SHOWS NOT ONLY IN TERMS
OF HIS FORGIVENESS BUT GOD'S
COMPASSION.
>> I SAW THAT INTERVIEW AND HE
WAS BLOWN AWAY.
HIS ABILITY TO FORGIVE IS NOT
JUST NATURAL VIRTUE, A GOOD GUY.
BUT HE UNDERSTANDS, HE BELIEVES,
THAT THERE IS ULTIMATE JUDGE AND
THAT IS GOD.
HE SAID IN SUCH CLEAR AND
PROFOUND LANGUAGE WE ALL HAVE
FREE WILL.
WE CAN CHOOSE TO USE IT FOR GOOD
OR BAD.
THIS YOUNG MAN ABUSED HIS FREE
WILL.
THEN HE SAID I'M GOING TO USE MY
FREE WILL FOR THE GOOD.
WHEN YOU HAVE THAT PROFOUND
CONVICTION OF WHO I AM, WHERE I
HAVE COME FROM, WHERE I'M GOING,
ULTIMATE JUDGMENT, IT'S EASIER
TO FORGIVE.
THAT'S A GIFT.
IT'S A GIFT OF FAITH.
AND WE SHOULD BE PRAYING FOR
EVERY SINGLE PERSON WHO DOESN'T
HAVE THAT IN THESE TOUGH TIMES
TO GET THAT.
IT'S A PROFOUND, WONDERFUL
THING.
>> WHAT IS THE ROLE OF FAITH AND
HEALING?
AND MAYBE IN PREVENTING FURTHER
TRANSLATION AROUND THE COUNTRY?
>> THAT'S AN EXCELLENT QUESTION.
WE CAN TALK ABOUT, LIKE OUR
PREVIOUS GUEST, THE CULTURAL
ISSUES.
ALL THIS TAKES A PLACE.
I HAVE GREAT RESPECT FOR JAMES
WHO TALKED ABOUT THAT BUT IN THE
END, NOT ONE SINGLE FACTOR WILL
PUT SOMEBODY OVER THE EDGE.
WE RECOGNIZE THERE'S MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES, A CULTURE OF
DEATH, INCLUDING VIDEO GAMES AND
OTHER THINGS, ALSO WHEN THE SOUL
GOES DARK, WHEN THE SOUL GOES
DARK, THAT'S WHEN THOSE OTHER
FACTORS BEGIN TO ADD UP TO
SOMETHING TRAGIC LIKE THIS.
THAT SOUL GOING DARK IN MY
OPINION IS ONE SOMEONE NO LONGER
HAS A PURPOSE FOR LIVING.
WHEN HUMANITY IS NOT WORTH THAT
MUCH, IF YOU'RE NOT LOVED, YOU
CANNOT LOVE.
ULTIMATELY IF YOU DON'T KNOW
YOU'RE LOVED BY GOD, IN MY
OPINION, THEN IT'S GOING TO BE
VERY HARD TO LOVE YOURSELF AND
OTHER PEOPLE.
>> THAT'S A VERY GOOD POINT
BECAUSE WHEN YOU READ ABOUT
UNDERSTANDING PURPOSE AND WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT IS VERY
KEY, BECAUSE WE'VE TALKED ABOUT
EVIL, WE'VE TALKED ABOUT THE
PSYCHOLOGICAL AND MENTAL
ILLNESS, BUT WHEN A PERSON LOSES
PURPOSE, THEY'RE A LOST SOUL AND
THE DARKNESS IS HARD TO
PENETRATE.
>> WE'RE ALL LOOKING FOR
PURPOSE.
EVEN I AS A PRIEST, I'M STILL
LOOKING FOR PURPOSE.
YOU LOOK FOR PURPOSE.
EVERY DAY YOU HAVE TO FIND WHAT
DOES GOD WANT FROM ME?
I MAKE A CHALLENGE TO THOSE
LISTENING TODAY.
AT THIS CHRISTMAS WHEN ALL THESE
FAMILIES WILL BE SUFFERING
BECAUSE THEY'VE LOST THEIR
CHILDREN, GET DOWN ON YOUR KNEES
OR SOME OTHER POSTURE BEFORE
OPENING GIFTS, BEFORE OPENING
GIFTS, MY MOTHER ACTUALLY
SUGGESTED THIS TO ME THIS
MORNING, AND TO SAY A PRAYER
WITH YOUR CHILDREN.
HOWEVER YOU CAN.
IF YOU DON'T KNOW HOW TO PRAY,
YOU'RE NOT A BELIEVER, A MOMENT
OF SILENCE, OF GRATITUDE, BUT
ABOVE ALL, TO SAY THANK GOD FOR
MY LIFE, THANK GOD FOR MY LOVED
ONES.
THAT'S HOW WE CAN CELEBRATE
CHRISTMAS THIS YEAR, MO
PROFOUNDLY THAN IN THE PAST.
I BET SOME OF THESE FAMILIES
WILL BE ABLE TO DO THAT
THEMSELVES.
>> THAT'S SO BEAUTIFUL, FATHER.
WHAT WILL YOU BE SAYING IN YOUR
SERVICES TODAY?
WHAT CAN YOU SAY?
>> YOU KNOW, I'LL BE TALKING
ABOUT IT IN A DIFFERENT WAY THAN
IF YOU WERE IN NEWTOWN.
WE'RE A LITTLE BIT DIDN'T.
I'LL TALK ABOUT HOW IS IT
POSSIBLE A LOVING AND GOOD GOD
COULD ALLOW THIS TO HAPPEN.
ABOUT THE FACT THAT GOD HIMSELF
ALLOWED HIS SON TO BE MURDERED
AND STOOD BY AND CRIED AS THE
EARTH WAS SHAKING.
I'M ALSO GOING TO TALK ABOUT
THAT WITH INDIVIDUALS, BECAUSE
IT'S NOT JUST A QUESTION, A
MESSAGE THAT COMES AND GOES BUT
WE HAVE TO DEAL WITH ON A
INDIVIDUAL LEVEL.
>> WHAT I'M HEARING FROM YOU,
THEN, WE'RE AT A POINT IN OUR
SOCIETY WHERE PAUL THE APOSTLE
TALKS ABOUT, THERE ARE PERILOUS
TIMES WHERE MEN ARE CAUGHT UP
WITH A LOT OF HATE.
DR. MARTIN LUTHER KING SAYS HATE
CAN'T DRIVE OUR HATE, ONLY LIGHT
CAN DO THAT AND THE CHURCH IS
THE CONSCIENCENESS OF THE WORLD.
>> I DON'T KNOW IF THEY'RE MORE
PERILOUS TIMES THAN IN THE PAST.
THE GOVERNMENT IS KEEPING ORDER
IN GENERAL SOCIETY BUT I THINK
IN ALL OF OUR LIVES THERE ARE
PERILOUS MOMENTS.
FOR THESE FAMILIES, THIS WAS THE
PERILOUS MOMENT.
FOR ALL OF US, AS WE GET CLOSE
TO OLD AGE, THERE ARE PERILOUS
MOMENTS.
OUR CULTURE IS MORE GODLESS THAN
EVER BEFORE IN THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA BUT IT COMES DOWN TO
MAKING DECISIONS.
AM I GOING TO LIVE JOY FULLY
TODAY?
IT COMES IN LOVING OTHERS AND
BEING LOVED.
>> FATHER, THANK YOU FOR YOUR
MESSAGES.
>> WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH AN
UPDATE FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, IN JUST TWO
MINUTES.
Hey! Did you know
that Honey Nut Cheerios
has oats that can help lower
cholesterol?
And it tastes good?
Sure does!
Wow.
It's the honey,
it makes it taste so...
Well, would you
look at the time...
What's the rush?
Be happy. Be healthy.
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'VE REACHED THE AGE
WHERE YOU DON'T BACK DOWN
FROM A CHALLENGE.
THIS IS THE AGE OF KNOWING
HOW TO MAKE THINGS HAPPEN.
SOWHY LET
ERECTILE DYSFUNCTION
GET IN YOUR WAY?
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT VIAGRA.
20 MILLION MEN ALREADY HAVE.
ASK YOUR DOCTOR IF YOUR HEART
IS HEALTHY ENOUGH FOR SEX.
DO NOT TAKE VIAGRA IF YOU TAKE
NITRATES FOR CHEST PAIN;
IT MAY CAUSE AN UNSAFE DROP
IN BLOOD PRESSURE.
SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE
HEADACHE, FLUSHING,
UPSET STOMACH,
AND ABNORMAL VISION.
TO AVOID LONG-TERM INJURY,
SEEK IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
FOR AN ERECTION
LASTING MORE THAN FOUR HOURS.
STOP TAKING VIAGRA
AND CALL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU EXPERIENCE
A SUDDEN DECREASE OR LOSS
IN VISION OR HEARING.
THIS IS THE AGE
OF TAKING ACTION.
VIAGRA.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR.
>>> THIS IS A FOX NEWS ALERT.
WE'VE HEARD FROM THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT, THE SANDY HOOK
STUDENTS WILL APPARENTLY BE BACK
IN SCHOOL BY WEDNESDAY.
AT LEAST SCHOOL WILL BE OPEN ON
WEDNESDAY.
BUT AT ANOTHER LOCATION.
NO WORD ON EXACTLY WHERE THE
STUDENTS WILL BE GOING TO SCHOOL
OR HOW MANY FEEL MENTALLY
PREPARED TO GO BACK BUT A THE
STATE AND GOVERNOR ARE TRYING TO
RETURN TO SOME LEVEL OF
NORMALCY.
>> WHAT THEY'RE DOING IS
ALLOWING THE OPTION FOR THOSE
THAT WANT TO FOCUS ON SOMETHING
ELSE.
IT'S DIFFICULT IN CONNECTICUT,
WE HAVE LOST A WEEK BECAUSE OF
HURRICANE SANDY SO THEY'RE
TRYING TO GET THE MINIMUM NUMBER
OF SCHOOL DAYS ON THE CALLER.
>> IT'S ONE OF THE BEST SCHOOLS
IN THE COUNTRY.
THAT WAS A PROFILE THE
PRINCIPAL, TO DEDICATED HER LIFE
TO EDUCATION AND GIVING HER
STUDENTS THE BEST AND EVEN
GIVING THE BEST IN SACRIFICING
HER LIFE FOR THEM.
>> THAT'S DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, AND
WE'VE LEARNED TODAY WHILE WE
WERE ON THE AIR THAT IT WAS PART
OF PROTOCOL THAT ONE OF THE
THINGS PRINCIPALS ARE TAUGHT
WITH NEW SAFETY MEASURES IS TO
CONFRONT AND CHALLENGE A
STRANGER.
WE'VE ALSO LEARNED FROM A FRIEND
OF PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG SHE
DID DRILLS FOR THE EVENT OF AN
ACTIVE SHOOTER COMING INTO THE
SCHOOL.
WE HAVE HER FRIEND ON "FOX &
FRIENDS" EARLIER ABOUT THIS.
>> SHE KNEW THE HEALTH AND
SAFETY OF HER CHILDREN WERE
PARAMOUNT.
I THINK THAT THE THING WE NEED
TO COME AWAY WITH IT THE FACT
SHE SAVED A GREAT MANY LIVES IN
TAKING THE ACTIONS SHE DID.
THE SURE THE HAD THE CAPABILITY
OF KILLING MUCH MORE AND THE
TRAGEDY WOULD HAVE BEEN FAR
WORSE.
WHEN WE TALK ABOUT THESE THINGS
IN OUR WILDEST DREAMS, DID WE
EVER THINK THE REALITY OF THIS
CONVERSATION HER AND I HAD WOULD
ENFOLD INTO REALITY AND CAUSE OF
LOSS OF HER LIFE, SHE'S TRULY A
HERO.
>> TRULY A HERO.
SHE KNEW EXACTLY WHAT SHE WAS
DOING WHEN SHE WENT AFTER THE
GUNMAN.
>> I ASKED THE FIRST SELECTMEN
WHAT THEY NEED AND HE SAID HOPES
AND PRAYERS.
HIS FIRST REACTION WAS PEOPLE
NEED TO LOOK OUT FOR SIGNS IN
THE MENTAL HEALTH COMMUNITY.
SAY SOMETHING, DO SOMETHING, IF
YOU SEE A DISTURBING
18-YEAR-OLD, 20-YEAR-OLD, TALK
TO SOMEONE.
>> IF YOU KNOW SOMEONE WHO IS
ISOLATED, REACH OUT TO THEM IS
WHAT WE CAME AWAY WITH.
THERE'S MORE "FOX & FRIENDS" IN
JUST TWO MINUTES.
t when I was i.
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
So I never missed a beat.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.