BNY Mellon Wealth Management
>> WE HAVE DONE EVERYTHING WE
CAN TO PEEL BACKLET ONION AND
LOOK AT THE CREVANCE AND THE
THAT DOESN'T INCLUDE THE
OUTSIDE OF THE BUILDING.
IT IS GOING TO BE A LONG PAIN
STAKING PROCESS.
>> HOUR BY HOUR NEW
INFORMATION COMING IN ON THE
DEADLIEST AND HEARTBREAKING
SCHOOL SHOOTING IN U.S.
HISTORY.
>> AS YOU KNOW BY NOW THE
GUNMAN OPENED FIRE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WHEN IT WAS ALL OVER 26 PEOPLE
WERE DEAD.
MOST OF CHILDREN.
YOUNGEST AM HAVE WAS JUST FIVE
YORES OLD.
ADAM HANS LANS THEN COMMITTED
CUSUDE.
NTHE NAMES OF THOSE KILLED ARE
EXPECTED TO BE RELEASED
SHORTLY .
THEY COMB THE SCHOOL IN AND
OUT FOR CLUES .
THEY HAVE GOOD EVIDENCE THAT
THEY HOPE WILL ANSWER
QUESTIONS.
>> I AM KEWILL WROITI AM UMA
WE HAVE SPECIAL EDITION OF
AMERICA'S NEWS HEAD QUARTERS
THAT STARTS RIGHT NOW.
>> WE'LL GO TO NEWTOWN
CONNECTICUT.
THEY ARE WRAPPING UP A PRESS
CONFERENCE.
ADAM LANZA WAS NOT LET INTO
THE SCHOOL VOLUNTARILY.
INSTEAD HE FORCED HIS WAY IN.
MOLLY IS STANDING BY IN THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL .
MOLLY?
>> THANK YOU, UMA.
THEY HAVEN'T GIVEN OUT A LOT
OF DETAILS.
WHAT THEY MEAN ON LANSA
FORCING HIS WAY IN.
NO ONE OPENED THE DOOR FOR
HIM.
AND HE WAS NOT STANDING IN THE
BUILDING WHEN THE DOORS WERE
LOCKING DOWN.
IT WAS A SITUATION WHERE HE
LIT RALGELY PUSHED HIS WAY
THE BUILDING SOMEHOW .
THERE WAS A QUESTION OF
WHETHER HE BROKE A WINDOW.
THERE IS REPORTS OF BROKEN
GLASS.
AND EVEN THE CHILDREN SAID
THRAMPT HE FORCEDS HAD WAY IN
THE BUILDING.
AND THE OTHER INFORMATION
COMING OUT.
ALL OF THE VICTIM'S BODIES AND
LOVE IT IS ONES HAVE BEEN ID'S
AND THEY ARE REMOVED FROM THE
BUILDING.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER WILL GIVE
FURTHER INFORMATION LATER THIS
AFTERNOON.
AND THE NAMES OF THE VICTIM
ARE COMING OUT LATER TODAY.
NINVESTIGATORS ARE PEELING
BACK THE UNYOB.
THEY WERE STILL ON SITE.
AND IT IS A LARGE CRIME SCENE.
NOT ONLY INSIDE BUT OUTSIDE OF
THE BUILDING.
THEY ARE LOOKING IN EVERY CAR
IN THE PARKING LOT AND LOOKING
FOR ALL OF THE CLUES TO
EXPLAIN HOW IT HAPPENED AND
WHY.
AND WHEN IT COMES TO THE
QUESTION OF WHY, THEY HAVE
EVIDENCE THAT THEY DISCOVER
THEY ARE HOLDING THE DETAILS
CLOSE TO THE VEST.
>> INVESTIGATORS IN THE CRIME
SCENE AND SCHOOL AND
SECONDARILY IN THE SECOND
CRIME SCENE WHERE THE FEMALE
WAS LOCATED AND DECEASED.
THAT PRODUCED GOOD EVIDENCE IN
THIS INVESTIGATION THAT
INVESTIGATORS WILL BE ABLE
TOUS AND PAINT THE COMPLETE
PICTURE HOW AND WHY THIS
OCCURRED.
THERE IS A SURVIVOR OF THE
SHOOTINGMENT AN ADULT SHOT.
AND AUTHORITIES BELIEVE IN THE
FOOT AND SHE WILL BE
INSTRUCTAL IN - SHOTTING.
>> AND THIS IS IT A COMMUNITY
IN DEEP MOURNING.
THEY HILD A PRAYER SERVICE.
WILL THEY HOLD MORE THROUGHOUT
THE WEEKEND?
>> THERE ARE A NUMBER OF
CHURCHES AND WHEN YOU DRIVE BY
THERE ARE SIGNS OUT PRAYER
SERVICE AT NOON OR 7.
AND ST. ROSE IS OPENED 24
HOURS IN THE SINCE THIS
HAPPENED.
THERE ARE FUNERALS AND
MEMORIAL SERVICES TO BE
PLANNED.
THE CHURCH COMMUNITY IS GOING
TO BE BUSY IN THE COMING WEEK:
AND THERE IS A MEMBER OF
SERVICES HELD AND VERY LIKELY
MANY DAYS TO COME.
>> THANK YOU FOR THE UPDATE.
>> WE HAVE THE VOFROM THE
POLICE SCANNER.
LET'S LISTEN .
(NO AUDIO)
WOO DON'T HAVE THE SOUND OF
THAT.
AND WE'LL GET IT BACK TO YOU.
IN THE MORNING PRESS
CONFERENCE.
OFFICIALS SAY THE
SUPERINTENDENT OF SCHOOLS
SHOULD BE ABLE TO PROVIDE MORE
CLARITY ABOUT THE MOTIVE.
AND SHE IS HEADED TO THE SCENE
RIGHT NOW.
AND WE EXPECT TO HEAR FROM HER
SOMETIME SOON .
IT HAS BEEN LITTLE MORE THAN
24 HOURS SINCE THE SHOOTING
AND THE NEWTUNE POLICE HAVE A
LONG INVESTIGATION AS THEY
PIECE TOGETHER WHAT HAPPENED
AND WHY.
THAT IS THE FUNDMENT WILL
QUESTION.
MARK FURMAN IS IT HERE AND HE
IS ON A TWO OR THREE SECOND
DELAY.
MARK, RIGHT TO THE QUESTION .
MANY PEOPLE ARING WHY?
WHAT CAN YOU TELL ME ABOUT THE
FACT THAT THE POLICE ARE NOW
DOING AND INVESTIGATE AND COME
UP WITH A CONCLUSION ONCE THEY
PIECE TOGETHER THE
INFORMATION?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW NORMALLY,
YOU HAVE THE SAME PROCEDURE
WITH A SINGLULAR HOMICIDE
REGARDS IF THE PUBLIC KNOWS.
THIS IS MULTIPLE HOMICIDE
VICTIMS AND YOU HAVE TO
DOCUMENT EACH PIECE OF
EVIDENCE.
AND THE ENTOUR SEASON IS
MEASURED AND GRAPPED AND PUT
ON PAPER MUCH LIKE A DRAFTS
MAN WOULD CREATE.
YOU HAVE TO PHOTOGRAPH EVERY
SINGLE PIECE OF EVIDENCE.
AND THE DOCUMENTED IN THERE
POSITION .
THERE IS FORENSIC.
AND BALLISTIC AND CASINGS ON
THE THERE ARE.
AND BULLIES THAT DAMAGED THEM
IN THE FLOOR AND WALL.
IT HAS TO UPON DOCUMENTED AND
WHY KNOW THE METHOD OF THE
UPON THOSE HAVE BEEN RECOVERED
AND IT SPEARS NO OTHERS ARE
LARGE.
ITS HAD TO BE DONE THIS WAY
NOT ONLY FOR FUTURE HISTORY.
BUT THIS IS THE WAY IT IS DONE
AND SADLY, I THINK EVERY
DETECTIVE AND COP ON THE JOB
VERY LONG IN ANY PLACE WHERE
THERE IS VIOLENCE, KNOWS WHAT
IT LOOKS LIKE.
THAT IS DISTURBING.
>> IT IS IT DISTURBING INDEED,
MARK.
ESPECIALLY FOR THE POLICE
OFFICERS AND DETECTIVES
WORKING IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
IT WAS SMALL AND ONLY VIOLENCE
THEY HAD WAS ONE.
AND IT NOT ONLY SHOCKS THE
SENSES.
BUT IT CAUSES AN EMOTIONAL.
AND WHAT IS GO THROUGH THEIR
MIND AS WHY GO TO A HORRIFIC
SCENE.
N50 THING AND FIRST BLUSH,
THEY DON'T HAVE THE VIOLENCE.
THIS IS NOT THE INNER STAVE
LOS ANGELES OR CHICAGO .
THIS IS NOT AN EVERYDAY
OCCURENCE.
AND SO THE INITIAL DETECTIVES
IN THE SMALLER COMMUPTS AND
LARGER COMMUNITY US THAT CAME
IN TO ASSIST.
IT IS HOCK ANDLET FIRST THING
THEY WILL THINK OF IS THEIR
OWN FAMILY AND THEIR RELATIVES
AND NEIGHBORS.
THEY ARE GOING TO THINK OF THE
FUTURE .
ANDING KNOW OF THE PRESIDENT
AND HOW WHAT THEY HAVE TO
PROFESSIONAL LOW .
AND TRY TACIOUS ARK TAG .
AND PERVELET AND TO WHY IT
OCCURRED.
MARK, IT IS IT EVERYTHING BOO
BY THE BOOK.
THIS GUY GAIN ENTRY FORCIBLY.
AND WHEN A SCHOOL DID
EVERYTHING RIGHT TO DEFEND
ITSELF.
HOW DO YOU RECOMMEND PROGRAMS
TO PROTECT ONE'S STOUNT.
FROM A ARMED AND AND
DETERMINED GUNMAN FROM
FORCIBLY ENTERING IN?
>> IT IS IT A SHAME THAT IT
HAS TO COME TO THIS.
BUT THIS SCHOOL DID QUITE A
BIT REALLY.
MORE THAN THE NORMAL HIGH
SCHOOL.
I WOULD SUSPECT THAT EVERY
SCHOOL SHOULD PROBABLY HAVE
SOMEBODY IN PLAINCLOTHES THAT
IS IT A TRAINED LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICER WITH
EXPERIENCE AND THE MATURITET
TO HANDLE PEOPLE AND CHILDREN
IN A WAY AND ACTUALLY SEE A
THREAT.
THAT IS NOT GOING TO STOP
ANYTHING.
LOOK AT THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES.
THE SECRET SERVICE KNOWS IF
THEY REDUCE THE THROATS, BUT
THEY CAN'T TOP THE THREATS
ANDS.
THAT BEING SAID.
YOU KNOW, I HAVE BEEN IN THE
COUNTRY OF ISRAEL AND SEEN HOW
THEY HANDLE SECURITY IN THAT
COUNTRY.
YOU CAN'T GET IN A MALL
WITHOUT IDENTIFICATION.
MEAN -- THEY ELIMINATE THIS
KIND OF A ACT.
THERE IS A PLACE IN BETWEEN WE
NEED TO BE.
NIT MAY NOT COME TO THAT IN
THIS COUNTRY BUT WILL BE
DISCUSSED WITH THE LAW MAKERS
AS WE MOVE BEFORE .
NNEW DETAILS ARE GIPPING TO
EMERGE WITH THE SHOOTER AND
HEY WHAT WE KNOW AT THIS
POINT.
HISES WERE DIVORTED IN A PROT
PEROUS AREA OF NEW TOUP
CONNECTICUT.
POLICE CONFIRM A WOMAN WAS
DEAD AND IT IS BELIEVED TO BE
HIS MOM.
THE GUNS WERE NANCY LANZA.
A FAMILY FRIEND IS QUOITED
WHEN THEY HEARD THE NEWS, THEY
KNEW IT HAD TO BE ADAM.
AND A RELATIVE SAID HE WAS NOT
WELL AND SUGGESTING SIGNS OF
MENTAL ILLNESS.
HE WAS MART AND ON THE HONOR
ROLL IN HOIL.
POLICE HAVE FOUND NO NOT.
BUT HE REPORTEDLY FORCED HIS
WAY IN WITH HIS WEAPON THE
SHOTTING AND WEARS BLACK
MATEAKS.
NAND 18 FOURTH GRADERS HIT IN
THE SCHOOL SHOTTING.
THE LIIER AN BARRICADED THE
DOR.
AND THE CLERK SAID SHE HAD THE
KIDS COLOR WHULE THIWAITED FOR
THE SCHEDULE TO END.
YOUR ADRENALIN GOES IT SCARY
FOR A LITTLE KID.
THEY WAPTED FOR A OFFICER
SLIDE IT TO MAKE SURE THE
POLICE WERE TELLING THE TRUTH.
NPRESIDENT OBAMA FINDS HIMSELF
IN THE ROLE OF CONSOLER AND
CHIEF AS HE LEADS A STUNNED
AND GRIVING NATION .
HERE IS THE REACTION FROM THE
NATION'S CAPITOL, JAMES, I
KNOW THAT YESTERDAY, THE
COUNTRY WATCH ANERNINGS --
AMERICAN PRESIDENT MAKE
EMOTIONAL COMMENTS.
>> IT IS BY AND LARGE OFFICIAL
WASHINGTON MOURNED AS ONE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA AS WE REPORTED
STRUGILED TO KEEP HIS
COMPOSURE IN THE BRIEFING ROOM
YESTERDAY.
CONTRAST OF THE EMOTIONALISM
AND THE COMPOSURE
LEDEMONSTRATED IN THE WOOKLY
SATURDAY ADDRESS WAS READILY
DISCERNABLE.
>> WHETHER IT IS IT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEW TON
OR SHOPPING MALL IN OREGON OR
TEMPLE OR MOVIE OR TREAT IN
CHICAGO.
>> MOVIE THEATER IN COLORADO.
COUNTLESS STREET CORNERS AND
PLACES LIKE CHICAGO AND
PHILADELPHIA, ANY OF THESE
NEIGHBORHOODS COULD BE OUR OWN
.
>> THE HORROR OF THE DAY SEEMS
SO UNBEARABLE SAID JONE --
JOHN BOEHNER.
AND FLAG WHITE HOUSE AND
CAPITOL BUILDING WERE ORDERED
TO HALF STAFF.
NANCY PELOSI SAID THE ENTIRE
WILL STAPPED AS A OF SUPPORT
TO THIS COMMUNITY.
HOMELAND SECURITY JANET
NAPOLITANO PLIDGED THEY WOULD
PLEDGE WHATEVER SUPPORT
NECESSARY NEEDED.
>> WE HEARD FROM RETOIRED MARK
KELLY WHO IS THE HUSBAND OF
GABBY GIFFORDS WHO SURVIVED
THE SHOOTING MASSACRE.
KILLY WAS ON A TRIP TO
BEIJING.
GIFFORDS SYNDS HER PRAYERS AND
HE SAID OUR LEAD ARES MUST DO
MORE THAN REGRET AND SORROW.
>> EVERYONE IS IS BOUND IN
GRIEF AND SORROW AND
BAFFLEMENT OVER THIS EVENT.
>> WHAT DO YOU DO WHEN A PLACE
OF LAUGHER AND LEARNING
BECOMES A SCENE OF HORROR?
WHAT IS YOUR YOUNG STERSE
THINKING.
>> EVEN THE YOUNGEST IS SURE
TO HEAR ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED,
WHAT DO YOU TELL THEM AND WHAT
ROLE SHOULD FAITH AND GOD PLAY
IN ALL OF THIS?
WE'LL TONY PERKINS AND WE HAVE
A CONVERSATION COMING UP WITH
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
LIEUTENANT PAUL SPRANCE COMING
NEXT.
[ Male Announcer ]
RED LOBSTER'S CRABFEST
ENDS SOON.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OURENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
STARTS WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND A CHOICE.
TAKE TYLENOL OR TAKE ALEVE,
THE #1 RECOMMENDED PAIN
RELIEVER BY ORTHOPEDIC DOCTORS.
JUST TWO ALEVE
CAN KEEP PAIN AWAY ALL DAY.
BACK TO THE NEWS.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Sharable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
VANCE COMING UP NEXT .
>> WE HAVE BREAKING NEWS IN
FROM WASHINGTON, SECRETARY OF
STATE HILLARY CLINTON JUST
FEIGNED.
THEY SAY THAT WHILE SUFFERING
FROM A STOMACH VIRUS SHE WAS
DEHYDRATED AND FAINTED AND
SUSTAINED A CONCUTION .
SHE WILL BE AT HOME AND
MONITORED BY HER DOCTORS.
SHE WILL CONTINUE TO WORK FROM
HEM AND STAYING IN REGULAR
CONTACT WITH THE STATE
DEPARTMENT AND OTHER OFFICIALS
.
SHE LOCKS FORWARD TO BEING
BACK IN THE OFFICE SOON.
WE HAVE NEWS THAT HILLARY
CLINTON FEIGNED IN THE STATE
DEPARTMENT AND SUSTAINED A
CONCUSSION .
WE'LL MONITOR THE STORY AND
BRING YOU MORE NEWS AS IT
BECOMES AVAILABLE ON THIS ONE.
>> STATE POLICE HAVE GOOD
EVIDENCE THAT MIGHT ANSWER
SOME QUESTIONS ABOUT THE
TRAGIC SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT.
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE, PUBLIC
INFORMATION OFFICE.
SIR, THANK YOU FOR JOINING US
THIS AFTERNOON.
AND OBVIOUSLY OUR HEART AND
PRAYERS GO OUT TO YOU NOT ONLY
FROM THE NATION BUT THOSE OF
US HERE IN FOX NEWINGS.
YOU HAVE A TASK BEFORE YOU AND
SAY IT IS AN ACTIVE
INVESTIGATION AND CASE; WHAT
DOES THAT MEAN?
WHAT ARE THEY DOING?
>> IT IS IT IMPORTANT TO NOTE
IT IS IT LIKE A ONION ASK WE
HAVE TO PEEL IT BACK LAYER BY
LAYER TEMPERATURE IS IT A PAIN
STAKING PROCESS AND TO MAKE
SURE WE EXAMINE THE SCENES AND
LOOK AT THE BACKGROUNDS OF
EVERYBODY.
AND SPEAK TO EVERY WITNESS
THAT CAN SHED LIGHT ON THE
CASE.
THERE IS IT A GREAT DEAL OF
WORK DONE.
>> SIR, LET ME YOU THIS.
I KNOW THE POLICE ARE NOT
REVEALING ANYTHING ABOUT
MOTIVE AT THIS POINT, BUT DO
YOU HAVE INFORMATIONINE THOUGH
YOU ARE NOLT REVEALING ON WHAT
LED TO THE MASSACRE?
>> I KNOW IN SOME OF THE WORK
DONE THERE IS INFORMATION AND
EVIDENCE UNCOVERED THAT OURORS
- INVESTIGATORS HAVE.
I DON'T HAVE INFORMATION THAT
WE ARE READY TO PUBLICIZE .
NIMENT TO YOU ABOUT YOUR SENSE
OF WHAT IS GOING ON IN THE
COMMUNITY RIGHT NOW?
IT IS A COMMUNITY THAT IS
SMALL TIGHT-KNIT AND NOT
ACCUSTOMED TO VIOLENCE.
AND THIS SHATTERS THEIR PEACE.
HOW ARE THEY COPING AND WHAT
KIND OF HELP ARE YOU NOW
RECEIVING FROM THE COMMUNITY?
IF IS MIND BOGGLING TO SEE AND
BELIEVE.
AND THE COMMUNITY CAME
TOGETHER LIKE I HAVE NEVER
SEEN BEFORE.
LOCALLY ALL OF THE PUBLIC
PERSONNEL.
AND OFFICIALS.
AND EVEN PEOPLE STOPPING BY
AND SAYING THANK YOU AND GOD
BLESS.
>> CERTAINLY, WE UNDERSTAND
THIS CRISIS AFFECTS EVERYBODY.
AND ALSO AFFECTS THE TOWN'S
PEOPLE.
THE TOWN SET UP A CRISIS
INTERVENTION TEEM AND CAN BE
REACHED FROM THE PHONE FOR THE
PEOPLE IN THE COMMUNITY.
>> DO WE HAVE THE NUMBER.
2003-270-4283.
203-270-4283.
IF YOU NEED TO DISCUSS AND
THERE IS PROFESSIONALS THAT
CAN HELP IN ANY WAY THEY CAN.
>> HOW IS THIS AFFECTING YOU
AND YOUR COLLEAGUES THERE THAT
HAVE TO BE THERE LITERALLY
24-7.
MONITORING THE SCENE AND
KNOWING THAT YOUR HEARTS ARE
BREAKING?
>> IT IS IT A TERRIBLE,
TERRIBLE TRAGEDY.
IT IS IT -- WHY ARE PROVIDING
PEOPLE WITH SUPPORT AND
COUNSELING AS WE CAN.
AND CERTAINLY THIS IS A HUGE,
HUGE TRAGEDY FOR EVERYBODY.
AND IT BREAKINGS OUR HEARTS
THAT THE FAMILIES ARE GOING
THROUGH WHAT THEY ARE GOING
THROUGH.
IT IS IT AN ATROCIOUS TRAGEDY.
NSO MANY REPORTS ARE COMING
IN.
AND WE HAVE TO VET THEM FOR
CONFIRMATION .
WAS THERE A CONFRONTATION
BETWEEN THE SHOOT ARE AND
OFFICIALS AT THE SCHOOL DAYS
PROIR TO THIS TRAGEDY THAT
UNFOLDED?
NI HAVE NO INFORMATION ON
THAT.
NOTHING WHAT SO EVER TO
INDICATE THAT.
NYOU HAVE ANY IDEA WHAT MAY
HAVE CAUSED ADAM LANSA SNOP
AND TAKE OUT HIS VIOLENCE OR
VENGEANCE ON INNOCENT
CHILDREN.
WE ARE LOOKING AT THE HISTORY
OF EVERYTHING AND WE ARE
TALKING AND SCRIMMAGING IN AND
ALL THAT THE MAY BE AFFECTUV.
AND WE WANT TO ANSWER EVERY
SINGLE QUESTION.
AND THIS WILL NOT BE COMPLOTE
WILL UNTIL WE HAVE ACHIEVED
THAT OBJECTIVE.
>> LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE, I
MENTIONED ALL OF US HERE ARE
EXPRESSING OUR SUPPORT AND WE
THANK YOU FOR DISCUSSING THE
SENTENCATIVE CASE WITH US.
- SENSITIVE CASE WITH US.
>> AFTER THE BREAK, MORE ON
WHAT WE KNOW ABOUT ADAM
LANZA'S BROTHER AND FATHER.
THE GRIEF OVER THE TRAGEDY
SPREADS FAR BEYOND NEWTOWN.
WE'LL HAVE THAT NEXT.
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
SOMETHING MADE YOUR JAW DROP?
CAMPBELL'S HAS 24 NEW SOUPS
THAT WILL MAKE IT DROP OVER,
AND OVER AGAIN.
♪
FROM JAMMIN' JERK CHICKEN,
TO CREAMY GOUDA BISQUE.
SEE WHAT'S NEW FROM CAMPBELL'S.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'VE REACHED THE AGE
WHERE YOU DON'T BACK DOWN
FROM A CHALLENGE.
THIS IS THE AGE OF KNOWING
HOW TO MAKE THINGS HAPPEN.
SOWHY LET
ERECTILE DYSFUNCTION
GET IN YOUR WAY?
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT VIAGRA.
20 MILLION MEN ALREADY HAVE.
ASK YOUR DOCTOR IF YOUR HEART
IS HEALTHY ENOUGH FOR SEX.
DO NOT TAKE VIAGRA IF YOU TAKE
NITRATES FOR CHEST PAIN;
IT MAY CAUSE AN UNSAFE DROP
IN BLOOD PRESSURE.
SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE
HEADACHE, FLUSHING,
UPSET STOMACH,
AND ABNORMAL VISION.
TO AVOID LONG-TERM INJURY,
SEEK IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
FOR AN ERECTION
LASTING MORE THAN FOUR HOURS.
STOP TAKING VIAGRA
AND CALL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU EXPERIENCE
A SUDDEN DECREASE OR LOSS
IN VISION OR HEARING.
THIS IS THE AGE
OF TAKING ACTION.
VIAGRA.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR.
>> WE'LL HAVE THE LATEST ON
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
MOLLY IS LIVE WITH A FEW OF
THE OTHER HEAD LINES .
INCLUDING BREAKING NEWS IN
EGYPT.
EGYPTIANS ARE NOW VOTING ON A
CONTROVERSIAL DRAFT
CONSTITUTION AFTER WEEKS OF
PROTEST.
NHUNDREDS OF EGYPTIANS WAITED
FOR HOUR TO GET THEIR VOTE IN
TODAY.
THE DRAFT HAS DEEPLY DIVIDE
THE COUNTRY WHEN PRESIDENT
MORSI POWER GRAB.
THERE IS A DISPUTE WHETHER THE
COUNTRY SHOULD GO TO
RELIGIOUSITATE UNDER MORSI OR
REMAIN MORE SECULAR.
>> THEY ARE CALLING ON
THINATIONINATION TO CONDEMN
THE ACTIONS.
VIOLENCE CONTINUES IN THE
COUNTRY HAS PRESIDENT ASSAUD
IS LOSING CONTROL.
MORE THAN 40,000 PEOPLE HAVE
BEEN KILLED.
>> A FUNERAL FOR A BRITISH
NURSE WHO WAS A VICTIM OF A
HOAX CALL.
THE NURSE TOOK THE CALL FROM A
PAIR OF AUSTRALIAN DJ'S.
ITEM DEEM WOULD A SUICIDE.
NTHE ENVELOPE ENVELOPED FOR A
MOMENT OF SILENCE.
THEYED THAT THE NATION COME
TOGETHER AND GRIEVE FOR THE
VICTIMS AND SURCIPH RADIORS.
UMA, AND KELLY, BACK TO YOU.
>> MANY, MANY QUESTIONS REMAIN
UNANSWERED ABOUT THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
THIDATING TOIL -- THE DEATH
TOLL STANDS AT 27.
THE BODIES HAVE BEEN REMOVED
FROM THE SCHOOL AND THEY ARE
IN THE MEDICAL EXAMININER'S
OFFICE.
ANOTHER VICTIM IS A RELATIVE
BELIEVED TO BE HIS MOTHER.
AUTHORITIES ARE SAYING THAT
THE GUNMAN IS TWINT YEAR OLD
ABAM LANZA.
HE FORCED HIS WAY IN THE
SCHOOL AND OPENED FIRE ON TWO
CLASSROOMS AND THEN KILLED
HIMSELF.
POLICE ARE SAYING THEY HAVE
GOOD EVIDENCE, AND THEY HOPE
WILL ANSWER SOME QUESTIONS.
NAMERICANS UNITED IN FAITH,
TRYING TO MAKE SENSE OF THIS.
HOW DOES MONOPOLY TRY TO MAKE
SENSE OUT OF SOMETHING SO
UNREEL.
SO MANY PEOPLE MAY BE FEELING
CONFUSED.
TONY PERKINS HEAD OF THE
FAMILY RESEARCH COUNCIL.
THANK YOU.
>> TONY, I KNOW IT IS IT EARLY
IN THE INVESTIGATION.
WE DON'T KNOW THE MOTIVE THAT
TRIGGERED THE MASSACRE YET.
MANY FEEL THEIR FAITH IS BEING
TASTED WHEN THEY SEE INNOCENT
VICTIMS GUNNED DOWN.
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THOSE ANGRY
WITH GOD .
>> IT IS IT THE MOST
CHALLENGING OF CIRCUMSTANCES.
I HAVE FIVE AND YOUNGEST IS
FIVE YEARS OLD AND ALSO I HAVE
BEEN IN ON THE SCREEN AS A
POLICE OFFICER.
BUT NOTHING THIS TRAGIC OF
OCCURENCE.
THIS COMES RAT -- AT A TIME
WHEN WE CELL WRATE JOY AND
PEACE ON EARTH AND CHRISTMAS.
BUT THE BACK IS THAT GOD SENT
HIS SON AND WE CELEBRATE THAT
AT CHRISTMAS TO REDEEM MAN.
AND THIS SPEAKS TO THAT ISSUE.
AND PEOPLE SEARCH AND THAT'S
WHY THE CHURCH DOORS WERE OPEN
IN CONNECTICUT AND ACROSS THE
COUNTRY, FOR PEOPLE TO TRY TO
MAKE SENSE BE OUT OF A SENSE
OF VIOLENCE.
IT IS APPROPRIATE TO THE
QUESTION OF WHY.
I DO THINK WE NEED TO BE OPEN
TO THE ANSWERS WE HEAR.
>> YOUR ORGANIZATION IS NOT
IMMUNE TO VIOLENCE EITHER.
WHAT DID YOU TELL YOUR FOLKS
AND HOW DID THAT MAKE YOU
FEEL?
>> AFTER THAT SHOOTING THAT
TOOK PLACE FOUR MONTHS AGO
TODAY, WE GATHERED OUR TEEM
TOGETHER AND WE PRAYED.
AT THAT POINT OUR COLLEAGUE
WHO WASED.
WE DIDN'T KNOW HOW SERIOUSLY
OR FAIR.
HE HAS RECOVERED FOR THE MOST
PART AND BACK AT WORK BUT HAS
SURGE RYES AHEAD OF HIM.
WE PRAYED FOR HIM AND THE
SHOOTER IN THAT CASE.
I TELL YOU, OUR TOME IS DOING
WELL BECAUSE WE HAD A STRONG
FAITH.
WE HAD A RELATIONSHIP WITH
GOD, AS CHRISTIANS THROUGH
JESUS CHRIST.
AND THAT EPI-- ENABLED US TO
GET THROUGH IT.
>> I CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT IT IS
LIKE FOR THE NATION.
WE TURN TO THE STRONG FAITH
COMPONENT AND THE
JUDEO-CHRISTIAN BACKGROUND,
OUR CHURCH DOORS ARE OPEN AND
PEOPLE MOURN AND WEEP
TOGETHER.
IT IS IT TO UNDERSTAND THE
THREAD THAT IS WOVEP THROUGH
OUR SOCIETY AND HOW IMPORTANT
IT IS FOR US.
NOT ONLY IN TIMES OF TRAGEDY.
BUT IT IS IT IMPORTANT TO
PREVENT SUCH TRAGEDIES.
>> THE DRESSED THAT AND QUOTED
A SCRIPTURE IN THEPPED OF HIS
ADDRESS IN THE PSALMS 147 3.
HE WILL BIND UP THE WOUNDS AND
HEEL THE BROKENHEARTED.
WHAT DO YOU SAY ABOUT THE
COMMANDER IN CHIEF AND
RELATING TO SCRIPTURE TO BRING
HEALING TO THE NATION?
>> I AM GRATEFUL FOR THAT.
I AM GRATEFUL HE DID THAT.
AND AGAIN, IT SPEAKS TO WHERE
WE TURN AS A PEOPLE, BOTH AS
INDIVIDUALLY ASK COLLECTIVELY
AS A SOIT IN THESE TIMES OF
GREAT CHALLENGE WHEN WE DON'T
HAVE SWARS.
RAY 20 YEAR OLD MAN GOES IN
AND KILLS INNOCENT, HELPLESS
CHILDREN.
YOU CAN'T MAKE SENSE OF THAT.
AND ONLY THING WE CAN DO IS
TURP TO THE CREATOR AND HIM
PUT THE PEACES BACK TOGETHER.
I MAY WE WILL TURN TO HIM IN
EARNEST THIS TIME.
>> TONY, WE APPRECIATE IT AND
BEE KNOW THAT THERE IS IT A
BIG JOB AS THE NATION TRIES TO
COME TOGETHER AND HEAL.
IT MAY TAKE DAYS OR MONTHS OR
YEARS BEFORE WE ARE THROUGH
IT.
>> SO 59 PEOPLE IN THE COUNTRY
ARING THEMSELVES THE SAME
QUESTION THIS MORNING.
WHY WOULD SOMEONE SHOOT UPAP
EPIIT TIRE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
AND KILLING SO PLANE INNOCENT
CHILDREN.
WE'LL TALK TO A FBI PROFILER
ACCIDENT NEXT.
-- NEXT.
SADLY, THEIR BROTHER'S
WHITE CHRISTMAS
JUST GOT "BLACKED OUT."
[ Brother ]
BUT IT'S THE FAMILY PARTY!
REALLY JINGLES YOUR BELLS,
DOESN'T IT?
MY GIFT TO YOU!
THE Capital One Venture Card!
FOR ANY FLIGHT, ANY TIME!
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE!
HOW ILLUMINATING.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
LET ME GUESS, AM
ON THE NAUGHTY LIST AGAIN?
HO HO HO!
I just served my mother-in-law
your Chicken Noodle soup
but she loved it so much...
I told her it was homemade.
Everyone tells
a little white lie now and then.
But now she wants
my recipe
[ clears his throat ]
[ softly ]
She's right behind me isn't she?
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
But when I was in an accident...
[ clears his throat ]
[ softly ]
She's right behind me isn't she?
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
So I never missed a beat.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.
>> WE HAVE BREAKING NEWS,
HILLARY CLINTON IS RECOVERING
AFTER SUSTAINING A CONCUSSION
EARLIER TODAY.
THE SECRETARY OF STATE HAD A
STOMACH VIRUS AND WAS
DEHYDRATED AND CAUSED HER TO
FAINT AND HIT HER HEAD.
SHE IS RECOVERING AT HOME AND
MONITORED BY HER DOCTORS.
AT THEIR RECOMMENDATION SHE
WILL WORK FROM HOME NEXT WEEK
.
>> SMALL TOWN COMMUNITY OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT IS
LOOKING TO PICK UP THE PIECES.
IT COULD TAKE MONTHS OR YEARS
BEFORE THEY FEEL SAFER IN THE
NEIGHBORHOODS.
WE'LL BRING IN MONICA CROWLEY
AND ALEN COMBS.
MONICA, LET ME BEGIN WITH YOU.
THE GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT
SAID EVIL ENTERED THE
COMMUNITY.
SHOULD EFFORTS BE STEPPED UP
TO HAVE OFFICERS AND METAL AND
PAT DOWNS?
>> WE'LL HAVE THE CONVERSATION
NOW UNFORTUNELY BECAUSE WE
HAVE SEEN A NUMBER OF THE
INCIDENTS AND A LOT OF SCHOOLS
HAVE A SECURITY MEASURES
ALREADY IN PLACE BECAUSE OF
THESE KINDS OF INCIDENTS IN
THE PAST.
SOMETIMES YOU DO HAVE POLICE
OFFICERS OR OTHER SECURITY
PERSONNEL.
THEY DO LOOK AT NINE TIME TIME
30 IN THE MORNING AND VISITORS
WHO WANT ENTER IN HAS TO BE
BUSSED IN.
WE WILL HAVE STEPPED UP
CONVERSATIONS ABOUT WHAT
NATIONS SHOULD DO TO KEEP
THESE KIPPEDS, SAFE.
>> I WANT TO ALEN AND MONITOR
SAID FROM THE GAMES BRADY - ON
JAMES BRADY ROOM.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN.
MEMBERS OF CONGRESS ARE
ECHOING THAT SAME SENTIMENT.
ALEN WHAT ARE YOU HEARING?
>> EVERYBODY IS TAKING A DEEP
BREATH AND TRYING TO PROCESS
WHAT'S HAPPENED BEFORE JUMPING
IN TO WHAT SHOULD WE DO OR
SHOULDN'T WE DO.
WE ARE TALK BEING PUBLIC
POLICY.
I KNOW THERE ARE MICHAEL
BLOOMBERG THAT WAS CRITICAL
FROM THE PRESIDENT FROM THE
LEFT ABOUT NOT FOC ING ENOUGH
ON THIS ISSUE.
BUT WE AS A NATION WANT TO
CATCH OUR BREATH.
ONE OF THE THINGS PEOPLE
TALKED ABOUT WAS THE NOTION OF
PERHAPS HAVING MORE GUARDS AT
SCHOOL.
I WOULDN'T PLIND IF MY
TAXPAYER DOLLARS WENT TO
HAVING MORE PERSONNEL AT
SCHOOLS THAT WERE IN A GUARD
SITUATION.
YOU HAVE TO WONDER,
INFORMATION ABOUT THIS COMES
IN COULD THIS BE PREVENTED.
HE FORCED HIS WAY IN WE FOUND
OUT THIS MORNING.
WE ARE TRYING TO GET OUR HEAD
AROUND HOW WE COPE AS A
NATION.
>> MONICA, YOU CAN WRITE LAWS
ALL YOU WANT IN WASHINGTON AND
HAVING POLICE OFFICERS TO
ENFORCE, BUT HOW DOES CONGRESS
MOVE THE BALL FORWARD IN
TRYING TO PREVENT THE
TRAGEDIES FROM UNFOLDING.
IF PEOPLE ARE HELL BENT ON
DESTROYING PEOPLE, THEY CAN DO
IT.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
IT GOES BACK TO THE BEGINNING
OF MANCOINED AND THE FIRST
MURDER WITH CAIN AND ABEL.
>> IT EXIST. WE CAN TRY TO
LIMIT THESE KINDS OF INCIDENTS
THROUGH INTERVENTION AND
CERTAIN LEGISLATION .
BUT THE BOTTOM LINE YOU CAN'T
PREVENT IT.
IT IS IT THE SAD TRUTH ABOUT
LIFE .
WE HAVE A TENDENCY TO TRY TO
LOOK AT A BIGGER EXMANATION
WHETHER IT IS IT THE CULTURE
OR MOVIES OR AND SOMETIMES
MOST SIMPLE EXPLANATION ISLET
EXPLANATION THAT THERE ARE
PEOPLE PROCESSED BY EVIL AND
THEY WANT TO COMMIT AN
UNSPEAKABLE ACT THEY WILL DO
IT AND THERE IS NOTHING THAT
SOCIETY CAN DO THOOTO PREVENT
IT WE CAN TRY TO LIMIT AND
MITIGATE THIS AND VENE, BUT IT
IS NEVER FOOL PROOF.
THAT IS IT A TRUISM OF LIFE
UNFORTUNATELY.
NLET ME JUMP IN HERE.
BUT ALEN, COULDN'T WE BE GOING
TO THE OTHER EXTREME?
CERTAINLY SCHOOLS ARE SUPPOSED
TO BE A SAFE HAVEN FOR OUR
CHILDREN.
AND A PLACE WHERE THEY ARE
SUPPOSED TO FEEL THEY CAN
REACH THE POTENTIAL IN A
POSITIVE AND HAPPY WAY THROUGH
A SAFE ENVIRONMENT.
WHAT MESSAGE DO YOU THINK IT
WOULD SEND IF WE POSTED GUARDS
AT ENTRY WAY AND GUNS AND
METAL DETECTORS IN EACH
SCHOOL.
NWE HAVE THEM IN AIRPLANES AND
FEDERAL BUILDINGS AND OTHER
PLACES.
I DON'T KNOW THRATHEY WOULD
OBJECT THEY WERE PROTECTED.
WE FEEL SAFER.
AND CERTAIN THINGS THAT THE
NRA WITH.
AND ALL SIDES CAN CONCUR ON.
SAFETY LOCKS ON GOOD AND
NATIONAL REGISTRY.
AND MORE QUICKLY, WE HAVE THE
TECHNOLOGY TO KNOW IF SOMEONE
GOES TO BUY A GUN.
AND THE ISSUE OF MENTAL
HEALTH, WHAT CAN WE DO TO
ADDRESS MENTAL HETTLE AND
TAKEAWAY THE STIGMA ON THOSE
WITH MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES.
THEY NEED TO COME FORWARD.
>> AND THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
ALWAYS GREAT TO SEE BOTH OF
YOU ON THIS VERY, VERY SAD
DAY, AS WE TAKE STOCK OF WHO
IS GOING O. THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
SO WE AS ADULTS, WE ARE
GRAPPLING WITH THE TRAGEDY.
IT IS IT HARD TO IMAGINE HOW
YOU EXPLAIN THE EVENTS OF
FRIDAY'S SHOOTING TO YOUR
CHILDREN.
WE'LL TALK TO THE EXPERTS
ABOUT THAT VERY FACT COMING
UP.
[ Male Announcer ] Alka-Seltzer
Plus PRESENTS THE Cold Truth.
I HAVE A COLD,
AND I TOOK NYQUIL,
BUT I'M STILL "STUBBED" UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT DOESN'T HAVE A DECONGESTANT.
NO WAY.
[ Male Announcer ] SORRY.
Alka-Seltzer Plus FIGHTS
YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A FAST ACTING
DECONGESTANT
TO RELIEVE YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
[ sighs ] THANKS!
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus.
♪ OH
WHAT A RELIEF IT IS! ♪
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
AND SAVE $1
VISIT Alka-Seltzer ON FACEBOOK.
I WISH I COULD KEEP IT
THIS WAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
NOW YOU CAN.
WITH THE CREST PRO-HEALTH
CLINICAL LINE.
USED TOGETHER,
THEY HELP KEEP YOUR TEETH
97% AS CLEAN
AS A DENTAL CLEANING.
THE TOOTHPASTE
ACTUALLY REDUCES PLAQUE.
AND THE RINSE REACHES ALL AREAS
AND IS CLINICALLY PROVEN TO
HELP PREVENT PLAQUE REGROWTH.
CREST PRO-HEALTH CLINICAL LINE.
TOGETHER, THEY HELP KEEP
YOUR TEETH
97% AS CLEAN
AS A DENTAL CLEANING.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
WELCOME BACK EVERYBODY.
THE ATTACK ON SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY IS NOT THE FIRST
MASS SHOOTING WE HAVE HAD IN
THIS COUNTRY.
LAST YEAR 12 PEOPLE WERE KILL
DOZENS MORE INJURED WHEN A
GUNMAN OPENED FIRE IN A
THEATER.
JAMES HOL MES WAS CHARGED WITH
ATTEMPTED MURDER.
AND A GUNMAN WAS WOUNDED IN
THE MIDDLE OF THE HOLIDAY
CROWD.
THE SUSPECT KILLED HIMSELF .
>> IMANNUALS OF CHILDREN CRY
STUNNED PARENTS FROM THE
SHOOTING.
AND NOW EXPLAIN THE SENSELESS
ACT OF VIOLENCE.
AND DOM NICK SPOKE WITH
EXPERTS ON HOW TO BREAK THE
TRAGIC NEWS AND DOWN FOR THE
CHILDREN YOU ARE SPEAKING
TOMPT DOM NICK, WHAT HAVE YOU
FOUND OUT?
>> PSYCHICOLOGIST SAY THIS IS
ONE OF THE HARDEST THUNGS TO
EXPLAIN TO CHILDREN OTHER THAN
THE DEATH OF THE IMMEDIATE
FAMILY.
MOST KIDS HEARD ABOUT THIS
THROUGH SOCIAL MEDIA.
AND NOW, THEY DON'T WANT TO
LET THE KIDS GET CARRIED AWAY
ON WHAT THEY READ ON LINE AND
TWITTER AND BOOK BOCK.
- FACEBOOK.
>> WHAT DID YOU SAY?
WERE YOU AFRAID IT WOULD
HAPPEN TO YOUR SCHOOL?
WHAT IF IT HAPPENED TO YOUR
SCHOOL.
THE TEACHERS WOULD STEP IN AND
THE POLICE WOULD BE THERE AND
MOMMA AND DADDY WOULD RUSH TO
THE SCHOOL.
AND SO DON'T BE AFRAID TO LET
YOUR EXPRESS AND PUT WORDS TO
AND TALK ABOUT WHAT IS INSIDE
OF HIM.
NAND LIKE WE WERE SAYING, IT
IS IT DETAIL THAT YOU ARE
SHARING WITH YOUR KIDS AND
WHAT IS APPROPRIATE.
AND IT IS IT A PARTICULAR
CHALLENGE FOR THOSE KIDS WHO
ARE THE SAME AGE AS THOSE
KIMED IN CONNECTICUT.
- KILLED IN CONNECTICUT.
>> YOUNG SCHOOL AGE MAY NOT
APPRECIATE THE PERMANENCY OF
DEATH.
WILL JOHNNY BE AT THE NEXT
SOCCER MATCH AND WILL I GET TO
SEE HIM.
THERE MIGHT BE REPEATED
QUESTIONS AND THEY MIGHT HAVE
TO TALK AND LET IT GO AND COME
BACK AGAIN.
>> YOU KNOW, KELLY, IN MANY
CASES OF YOUNG CHILDREN IT
BEING BE THE FIRST TIME THEY
ENCOUNTER THEIR OWN SENSE OF
MORTALITY.
KEEPING STRUCTURE AND ROUTINE
AT A TIME LIKE THIS AND THEY
KNOW THERE IS CONSISTENCY IN
LIFE.
KELLY.
NDOM NICK, THAT IS GOOD ADVICE
AND THANK YOU FOR THAT, SIR.
>> SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SHOOTING IS THE SECOND MASS
SHOOTING THIS YEAR.
AND FOR THOSE WHO EXPERIENCED
COLUMBINE SHOOTING IN 1999.
THESE EVENTS ARE ALL TOO
FAMILIAR FROM THEM.
UP NEXT THE PERSPECTIVE FROM
THE PRINCIPAL OF COLUMBINE
HIGH SCHOOL.
>> IT IS CLOSE TO HOME AND
JUST MAKES US REALIZE HOW
VULNERABLE WE ARE AS A
SOCIETY.
NOTE SNOTE
THE ♪
>>  THE TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT
HITTING CLOSE TO HOME FOR
SURVIVORS OF THE COLUMBINE
HIGH SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
COLORADO.
A REPORTER TALKED WITH SCHOOL
LEADERS THERE AND PARENTS WHO
WERE THERE IN 1999.
>> JUST LIKE TO START OFF BY
JUST OFFERING OUR CONDOLENCES
AND PRAYERS TO THE PEOPLE IN
CONNECTICUT.
>> Kelly: DOING HIS BEST TO
FIGHT BACK TEARS, FRANK
DEANGELUS TALKED ABOUT SHOCK
AND SADNESS.
>> CLOSE TO HOME AND JUST
MAKING US REALIZE HOW
VULNERABLE WE ARE AS A
SOCIETY.
>> Kelly: IT WAS ALMOST 14
YEARS AGO WHEN TWO GUNMAN
ENTERED COLUMBINE AND
SLAUGHTERED 13 STUDENTS AND TO
DEANGELUS, THE CONNECTICUT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HAS ENTERED
A CLIB.
>> WE HAVE TO STAND UP AND
SAYING ENOUGH IS ENOUGH WHAT
IS WRONG WITH OUR SOCIETY.
AND AGAIN, THERE'S NOT ONE
RIGHT ANSWER.
>> Reporter:  THIS PRINCIPAL
BELIEVES A LOT OF LESSONS
LEARNED.
BUT THE ANSWER DOES NOT LIE IN
SPENDING MORE MONEY ON