PRIME GERALDO WILL DO SPECIALS
AND JANINE PIRO WILL BE DOING
STUFF.
STAY WITH FOX NUSE CHANNEL
THROUGHOUT THE THE WEEKEND.
I AM SORRY I HAVE TO REPORT IT
HORRIBLE STORY SPOUT OFF ABOUT
THE FACTOR.
OREILLY NEWS.COM.
WORD OF THE DAY.
NO BILLINGS WHEN RUNNING THE
FACTOR.
I AM BILL O'REILLY.
REMEMBER THE SPIN HERE.
WE ARE DEFINITELY
>>> THIS REMAINS A FLUID
SITUATION, WITH PIECES OF
INFORMATION CONTINUING TO
EMERGE.
AND OUR OWN RICK LEVENTHAL SON
THE SCENE.
RICK HAS THE LATEST.
>> SCHOOLS ARE ON LOCK DOWN.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER AND
INVESTIGATORS ARE COLLECTING
EVIDENCE AND GOING TO THE
GRUESOME TASK OF IDENTIFYING
BODIES OF 27 VICTIMS,
INCLUDING THE SHOOTER WHO SHOT
HIMSELF AFTER KILLING SIX
ADULTS AND 20 KIDS, INSIDE
THAT HAVE SCHOOL.
WHAT WE'RE NOW BEING TOLD,
WHAT I'VE BEEN TOLD BY
INVESTIGATORS AND FEDERAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT SOURCES IS THAT
SHOOTER KILLED HIS MOTHER,
SHOT HER IN THE HEAD IN THE
HOME THEY SHARE, HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT THIS
MORNING.
THEN, TOOK THE THREE WEAPONS
SHE OWNED, A GLOCK, A
SIG SAUER HANDGUN, AND HE
GAINED ENTRANCE TO THE SCHOOL
THROUGH SECURITY, AND THEN,
OPENED FIRE.
WE KNOW POLICE RESPONDED.
YOU HEARD THE TAPES WE KNOW
THEY CALLED IN REENFORCEMENTS.
OFFICERS DIDN'T WAIST TIME.
THEY WENT INTO THE SCHOOL GOT
KIDS IN THE SURVIVORS OUT OF
THE SCHOOL, MOVED THEM TO A
NEARBY FIRE HOUSE, SET UP AS A
STAGING AREA THAT.
IS WHERE FRANTIC PARENTS WERE
DIRECTED TO COLLECT THEIR
CHILDREN, AND TAKE CARE OF
THEIR KIDS, AND GET THEM HOME,
SAFELY, SEAN.
>> SEAN: A COUPLE THINGS
EMERGED ONE TEACHER HAS GN ON
RECORD.
THE SCHOOL HAD ADDED IN
SECURITY.
YOU WOULD HAVE TO BE
IDENTIFIED, THEN BUZZED INTO
THE SCHOOL.
AT THIS POINT THE SHOOTER
IMMEDIATELY WENT TO THE
ADMINISTRATION AND WHAT WE
LEARN STHAD THIS IS DURING
MORNING ANNOUNCEMENTS.
AT THAT TIME, SOMEONE KEPT UP
ANNOUNCEMENT, THAT SERVED AS A
WARNING FOR PEOPLE IN THE
SCHOOL, AND A LOT OF OTHER
STORIES OF HEROISM, INCLUDING
CUSTODIAN AND TEACHERS WHACHL
HAVE YOU HEARD TODAY?
>> WE HAVE HEARD SOME OF THE
CHILDREN AND ADULTS IN THE
LOUD SPEAKER SYSTEM,
APPARENTLY AS SHOOTING WAS
UNFOLDING BECAUSE THEY'RE
COMING OVER THE SPEAKER.
OF COURSE, CHILDREN AND
TEACHERS ALSO HEARD GUNSHOTS
IN THE SCHOOL.
AND MANY OF THEM TOOK COVER,
SOME LOCKED THEMSELVES INTO
CLASS ROOMS OTHERS RAN.
LEAST ONE DWRUNG BOY, SIX
YEARS OLD, WATCHING HIS
TEACHER SHOT, THEN RUNNING FOR
SAFETY OUT OF THE CLASSROOM,
THINGING CLASSMATES WITH HIM.
>> YES.
YES..
>> SEAN: I READ THAT.
>> YES. WE DON'T KNOW HOW THIS
SHOOTER GOT INTO THE BUILDING
WHETHER THEY BUZZED HIM IN
BECAUSE HIS MOTHER WORKED
THERE OR SOMEHOW GOT AROUND
SECURITY, SEAN.
>> SEAN: RICK, WE'LL BE
CHECKING IN THROUGHOUT THE
NIGHT.
JOINING ME NOW IS CONNECTICUT
STATE REP STIFF WITH US AND
HIS TWO NIECES AND NEPHEWS
WERE AT THE SCHOOL AT THE TIME
OF THE SHOOTING.
THANKS FOR JOINING US TONIGHT.
FROM WHAT I UNDERSTAND, THE
COMMUNITY OF ABOUT WHAT?
27,000 PEOPLE, FAIRLY WELL TO
DO, 60 MILES NORTHEAST OF NEW
YORK CITY.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT THE
COMMUNITY?
WHAT YOU KNOW FROM YOUR NIECES
AND NEPHEWS?
>> WELL, SEAN, THANK YOU.
YOU'RE CORRECT.
IT'S A GREAT TOWN, AND I CAN'T
STOP THINKING ABOUT ACTUALLY
LAST NIGHT, LAST NIGHT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HAD THE
HOLIDAY CONCERT A TENDED.
MY TEENAGERS WERE PART OF THE
CHOIR.
AND INNOCENCE, I GO BACK TO
FAMILIES ON THE STAGE AND
SIBLINGS RUNNING THROUGHOUT
THE AUDITORIUM, 12 HOURS LATER
THE TRAGEDY OCCURRED.
>> YES.
AND HAVE YOU SPOKEN TO ANY OF
THE OTHER PEOPLE IN TOWN?
ANY OTHER STORIES WE'VE BEEN
HEARING INCLUDING THE
CUSTODIAN?
WE HAVE A TEACHER ON TAPE I'LL
SHOW IN JUST A MOMENT.
THE LENGTHS TO WHICH PEOPLE
WENT TO PROTECT THESE CHILDREN
IT WAS PRETTY AMAZING.
>> IT WAS INCREDIBLE.
I KNOW ONE OF MY NIECES WAS IN
THE LIBRARY.
AND THEY WERE USHERED INTO A
CLOSET TO PROTECT THEM.
MY SISTER DID SOMETHING WHICH
I DON'T THINK COY HAVE DONE.
SHE WAS ON HER WAY TO THE
SCHOOL AND THERE ARE FIVE,
FOUR BOY BOYS AND A GIRL IN
FIRST GRADE RUNNING UP THE
STREET.
AND SHE STOPPED AND PICKED
THEM UP, NOT KNOWING WHAT IS
GOING ON.
AND ONE OF THE BOYS SAID THAT
THERE WAS A, SOME ONE WITH A
GUN TRYING TO KILL THEM IN THE
SCHOOL.
SHE SHE CULLED THE SCHOOL, NO
ANSWER.
THE POLICE DEPARTMENT, SHE
STAYED WITH THEM BECAUSE THE
POLICE DEPARTMENT EMPTIED OUT.
AND STAYED WITH THEM, NOT
KNOWING THE FATE INVOLVED OF
THE KIDS IN THE SCHOOL.
>> SEAN: JUST SENSELESS, EVIL.
AND OUR THOUGHTS AND PRAYERS I
HOPE YOU KNOW, FROM THE
COUNTRY ARE WITH YOUR
COMMUNITY TONIGHT.
THANK YOU.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> SEAN: THANK YOU FOR JOINING
ME.
WE GO BACK NOW TLOIF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
FOX NEWS'S OWN BILL HAMMER IS
STANDING BY TO GIVE US
DETAILS.
BILL?
>> YES.
SEAN, GOOD EVENING.
THE STORY IS NOT EVEN 12 HOURS
OLD.
THE NEWS BROKE AT 9:30 THIS
MORNING.
WE'RE ON THE AIR LIVE AT 10:15
EASTERN TIME.
THE NEWS JUST STARTED TO COME
ACROSS THE WIRE, AND FRANKLY
AT THE TIME WERE TOLD ONE
PERSON HAD BEEN SHOT IN THE
FOOT AND BEING TREATED IN A
LOCAL HOSPITAL.
THERE IS VERY LITTLE NEWS
AFTER THAT.
THAT WENT ON FOR A
CONSIDERABLE AMOUNT OF TIME.
45 NINZ HOUR WE STARTED
LEARNING ABOUT THIS, NOW, WHEN
YOU GO BACK AND PIECE TOGETHER
THIS IN YOUR MIND, THE REASON
FOR THAT IS OBVIOUS NOW.
THERE WERE NO OTHER INJURIES.
WERE JUST DEAD BODIES INSIDE
OF THE SCHOOL HERE IN
CONNECTICUT.
THE POLICE WERE THERE, JUST
ABSORBING THIS INFORMATION
GOING THROUGH FROM ROOM TO
ROOM.
AND TRYING TO MAKE SURE THAT
THE KILLER THE GUNMAN, WAS
ACCOUNTED FOR AND NO ONE ELSE
IS INSIDE.
WE'VE BEEN TELD NOW MANY OF
THE CHILDREN WERE TOLD TO
CLOSE THEIR EYES AND RUN.
TO GET OUT OF THE BUILDING AND
MAKE SURE THEY DID NOT LOOK
AROUND WHERE THEY WERE.
I SPOKE TO A WOMAN ABOUT AN
HOUR AGO. SHE HAS A DAUGHTER
WHO IS OKAY.
SHE TOLD HER MOTHER THEY WERE
LET OUT OF THE BACK DOOR OF
THE SCHOOL TO MAKE SURE THAT
THEY DID NOT PASS BY ANY OF
THE DEAD CHILDREN WHO ARE
LYING THERE ON THE CLASSROOMS.
WHERE THEY HAD GONE TO SCHOOL
HERE, THESE STORIES ARE JUST
SO CHILLING, SEAN.
>> SEAN: I'VE HEARD INTO THAT.
>> WE'RE LEARNING THIS FOR THE
FIRST TIME, JUST BLOWS YOUR
MIND THE LEVEL OF EVIL THAT
ROLLED THROUGH THIS TOWN
TODAY.
>> SEAN: I DON'T THINK I CAN
SAY IT ANY BETTER THAN THAT,
BILL.
THE IDEA SOME OF THE KIDS WERE
TOLD TO CLOSE YOUR EYES, AS
THEY WALKED THEM OUT, THERE
ARE THREE STORY THAT'S STRUCK
ME TODAY THAT CAME TO PASS.
ONE IS THE 6-YEAR-OLD WE JUST
MENTIONED.
THAT AS THE SHOOTER WAS
SHOOTING HE GRABBED HIS
FRIENDS AND HE RAN OUT OF THE
CLASSROOM.
ANOTHER, A CUSTODIAN RUNNING
UP AND DOWN THE HALLS TO WARN
PEOPLE.
WE HAVE A TEACHER NUMEROUS
STORIES OF TEACHERS HIDING
KIDS IN CLOSETS AND DOING
EVERYTHING THEY CAN DO, AND
LOCKING INDOORS AND LOCKING
DOORS, ONE TEACHER INTERVIEWED
TONIGHT.
I WANT TO PLAY THAT FOR YOU.
>> I TOOK ONE OF MY STUDENTS
ON TOP OF THE TOILET.
I KNEW WE HAD TO GET IN THERE.
TELLING THEM IT'S GOING TO BE
OKAY.
YOU'RE GOING TO BE ALL RIGHT.
I PULLED A BOOK SHELF IN FRONT
OF IT.
WE WERE BARRICADED AND I
TURNED LIGHTS OFF.
>> DID YOU TELL THEM TO BE
QUIET?
>> I TOLD THEM.
BE QUIET.
WE HAVE TO BE ABSOLUTELY QUIET
BECAUSE I WAS JUST AFRAID IF
HE DID COME IN, HE WOULD HEAR
US AND START SHOOTING THE
DOOR.
I SAID JUST BE ABSOLUTELY
QUIET.
I SAID THERE ARE BAD GUYS OUT
THERE.
WE NEED TO WAIT FOR THE GOOD
GUYS.
AND I JUST -- HIDE.
I WANTED US TO BE OKAY.
AND I AM SO SADDENED THERE ARE
PEOPLE WHO, IN THIS SITUATION,
ARE NOT OKAY.
AND MY HEART GOES OUT TO
ANYONE WHO KNEW THEM.
AND WAS PART OF THEIR LIVES.
I KNLT IMAGINE.
-- CAN'T IMAGINE.
>> SEAN: IT'S HARD TO CALL TO
GRIP WAS THIS EVIL.
THESE PARENTS, I'M SURE MANY
OF THEM HAVE BOUGHT CHRISTMAS
GIFTS FOR LITTLE CHILDREN.
AND NOW, THEY'RE PLANNING
FUNERALS AND CHRISTMAS EVE AND
CHRISTMAS DAY IS GOING TO
COME.
THEY'RE NOT GOING TO HAVE
THEIR KIDS HOME.
>> YOU KNOW, SEAN, A FEW OTHER
THINGS.
WE'RE JUST NOW LEARNING ABOUT
THE VICTIMS.
AND THIS IS GOING TO BE THE
NEXT WAVE IN THIS STORY.
IF YOU THINK IT'S SAD NOW,
HANG ON.
BECAUSE NOW, WE'RE GOING TO
MEET THE PEOPLE WHO WERE
KILLED INSIDE OF THE BUILDING.
WE'RE TOLD THE PRINCIPAL,
SHE'S BEEN IN THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT YEARS.
I DON'T WANT TO GIVE HER NAME
OUT.
IT HAS NOT BEEN MADE PUBLIC
YET.
AGE 47.
TWO DAUGHTERS AND SHE LEAVES
THEM BEHIND.
A HUSBAND.
AND AND I EXPECT STATE POLICE
HERE TO GIVE POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATION OF THE BODIES
INSIDE OF THE BUILDING.
I MENTIONED THIS EARLIER.
WHEN YOU'RE FIVE YEARS OLD,
YOU ARE 10, 11 DIAS WAY FROM
CHRISTMAS, YOU'RE BELIEVING
SANTA CLAUS IS GOING TO BE IN
YOUR HOUSE.
AND TODAY, THE DEVIL KALE CAME
TO THIS TOWN.
THIS TOWN HAS TO LIVE WITH IT
FOR THE REST OF THEIR LIVES.
>> WE APPRECIATE IT THIS, IS
NOW THE SECOND DEADLIEST
SHOOTING IN U.S. HISTORY.
THE INVESTIGATION IS UNDERWAY.
A SOURCE JUST TOLD THE AP TWO
GUNS WERE FOUND INSIDE OF THE
SCHOOL.
WE'LL UPDATE WHEN YOU WE
RETURN TWO, VETERAN LAW
ENFORCEMENT MEMBERS WILL JOIN
ME TO WALK US THROUGH DAY AS
HEAD WAS AZ WE CONTINUE OUR
COVERAGE HERE ON THE FOX NEWS
CHANNEL.
Sometimes what we suffer from
Is bigger than we think ...
like the flu.
With aches, fever and chills-
the flu's a really big deal.
So why treat it like
it's a little cold?
There's something
that works differently
than over-the-counter
remedies.
Prescription TAMIFLU attacks
the flu virus at its source.
So don't wait. Call your
doctor right away.
TAMIFLU is prescription
medicine for treating the flu
in adults and children
one year and older
whose flu symptoms started
within the last two days.
Before taking TAMIFLU tell your
doctor if you're pregnant,
nursing. have serious
health conditions,
or take other medicines.
If you develop an allergic
reaction, a severe rash,
or signs of unusual behavior,
stop taking TAMIFLU and call
your doctor immediately.
Children and adolescents in
particular may be at an
increased risk
of seizures, confusion
or abnormal behavior.
The most common
side effects are
mild to moderate nausea
and vomiting.
The flu comes on fast,
so ask your
doctor about TAMIFLU.
Prescription for flu.
>>> WE HAVE ENDURED TOO MANY
OF THESE TRAG DEC IN THE PAST
FEW YEARS AND EACH TIME I
LEARN THE NEWS, I REACT NOT AS
A PRESIDENT BUAS ANYBODY ELSE
WOULD, AS A PARENT.
AND THAT WAS ESPECIALLY TRUE
TODAY.
I KNOW THERE IS NOT A PARENT
IN AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL
THE SAME OVERWHELPING GRIEF
THEY DO.
THE MAJOR OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5-10 YEARS OLD .
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
ATHEM.
BIRTH DAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS, KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS, MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES TO HELPING
OUR CHILDREN FULFILL THEIR
DREAMS AND SO OUR HEARTS ARE
BROKEN TODAY.
MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF
THE VICTIMS AND IN THE WORDS
OF SPRITZER.
HEAL THE BROKENHEARTED AND
BIND UP THEIR WOUNDS.
>>> THAT WAS PRESIDENT OBAMA
EARLIER EMOTIONS RUNNING HIGH
AS THE COUNTRY COPES WITH THE
SENSELESS TRAG 20 CHILDREN AND
6 ADULTS AND BREAKING MOMENTS
AGO, A SOURCE TOLD THE AP MORE
THAN TWO GUNS WERE FOUND IN
THE SCHOOL.
IT WAS RECENTLY REPORTED THAT
TWO HANDGUNS WERE FOUND.
FEDERAL AUTHORITIES ARE
WORKING TO TRACE THOSE FIRE
ARMS.
JOINING ME TO HELP EXPLAIN
WHAT THE POLICE DO NOW AND
WHERE THEY GO IN THE
INVESTIGATION .
ROD WHEELER WAS TEACHING A
COURSE ON ACTIVE SHOOTERS.
AND FORMER NYPD DETECTIVE JOE
COFFEY.
HE SUPERVISED THE LATE SON OF
SAM INVESTIGATION IN THE
1970S.
OBVIOUSLY THIS KID HAS
EMOTIONAL PROBLEMS AND YOU
HAVE TO BE CRAZY AND/OR EVIL
TO KILL -- THESE ARE BABIES.
KINDERGARTENERS HERE.
YOU DEALT WITH THIS.
>>> THIS GUY IS A SOC PATH
LIKE ALMOST ALL OF THEM ARE.
PEOPLE SAY THEY ARE MENTALLY
ILL AND THEY PROBABLY ARE.
PEOPLE LIKE HIM, THEY ARE
SOCIO PATHS.
>>> MEANING THEY DON'T CENTER
A CONSCIENCE AND A SENSE OF
RIGHT AND WRONG AND NO GUILT
ASSOCIATED WITH BERKOWITZ.
SON OF SAM.
ED HIM MOTIVE.
MY MOTHER PUT MEAVE UP FOR
ADOPTION.
IT IS CRAZY.
>>> IT IS IT FALLING BACK ON
AN EXCUSE.
THEY ARE SOCIO PATHS.
>>> THEY ARE OFFERING
COUNSELING TO FIRST RESPONDERS
BECAUSE THE SCENE WAS SO
HORRIFIC AND THE FAMILIES, I
DON'T KNOW HOW AS A PARENT AND
I AM A PARENT OF TWO KIDS DO
YOU EVER OVERCOME I DON'T KNOW
HOW THE RECOVERY COMING IN.
BUWHAT ARE POLICE DOING.
THEY HAVE TO GO THROUGH THE
HORROR OF IDENTIFYING THE
BODIES AND GOING AND TELLING
THE PARENTS, WHERE DO THEY GO
FROM HERE?
>>> THEY HAVE TO RESPOND TO A
CALL THAT INVOLVES CHILDREN.
IT IS ONE OF THE WORST THAT A
POLICE OFFICER CAN GO TOMPT
WHEN YOU SEE THE CARNAGE THAT
THE OFFICERS SAW TODAY.
IT IS UNBELIEVABLE AND THEY
WILL HAVE CONFLICT AS A MATTER
OF FACT.
WHAT THE POLICE ARE DOING
RIGHT NOW, THERE IS A NUMBER
OF THINGS.
A NUMBER OF UNANSWERED
QUESTIONS THAT WE ARE TRYING
TO FIGURE OUT.
WHAT WAS THE MOTIVE BEHIND THE
GUYS ACTION.
GRANTED HE WAS A SOCIO PATH.
BUTHERE IS IT ALWAYS A SPARK
AND WARNING SIGNS IN EVERYONE
OF THESE CASES.
RIGHT NOW THE INVESTIGATORS
AND ATF.
THEY ARE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHERE THESE GUYS GOT THE
AMMUNITION FROM AND WEAPONS
FROM WHY DID HE SELECT THIS
SCHOOL AND CLASSROOM?
WE ARE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
ALL OF THAT NOW.
>>> YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE AN
INVESTIGATOR TO PEACE TOGETHER
THE FACT HIS MOTHER WORKED
THERE AND HE KILLED HIS MOTHER
AND WENT TO THE SCHOOL.
HE SUFFERED FROM PERSONALITY
DISORDER OR PERHAPS TUST --
AUTISTIC OR MEDICATION MAYBE.
WE'LL CHECK IN WITH MEDICAL
EXPERTS LATER.
>>> IN MY BUSINESS AND LAW
ENFORCEMENT AREA.
YOU CONFRONT EVIL.
HE WAS THE EPITOME OF EVIL AS
TIMOTHY MACVEIGH AND
BERKOWITZ.
THEY ARE CREATURES THAT
SHOULDN'T WALK THE EARTH.
AND THESE TYPE OF PEOPLE, THEY
ARE IMMUNE TO RIGHT AND WRONG.
THEY HAVE NO CLUE.
>>> ONE LAST QUESTION.
WHEN A COP WALKS IN AND SEES
THAT, COPS SEE A LOT IN THE
COURSE OF THEIR CAREER.
>>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>>> THIS HAS GOT TO BE
PARTICULARLY TRAUMATIC EVEN
FOR THEM.
THEY HAVE TO GO IN THERE AND
IDENTIFY AND PEOPLE HAVE TO
CLEAN THIS UP.
IT IS TO BE DIFFICULT FOR
EVERYBODY INVOLVED IN EVERY
LEVEL.
>>> IT IS IT THE WORST
SCENARIO THAT WE CAN FIND
OURSELVES N. ALL POLICE
OFFICERS ARE PROFESSIONALS AND
WE ARE TRAIN TOD RESPOND AND
WE HAVE TO RESPOND IN THESE
SITUATIONS.
BUWHEN IT INVOLVES CHILDREN IT
IS THE WORST THING YOU CAN
EVER EXPERIENCE.
WE STILL HAVE TO GO IN AND
REMEMBER THEM.
WHEN THE FIRST OFFICER GOT ON
THE SCENE, THEY HAD NO
ICALLYCLUE WHETHER THER HAD
KILLED HIMSELF.
THEY HAVE TO ATTEND TO THE
INJURED BUHAD AN ACTIVE
SHOOTER TO TAKE OUT.
IT IS A TERRIBLE SITUATION TO
DEAL WITH, SEAN.
>>> I KNOW ONE THING, THESE
POLICE OFFICERS, THEY WILL
LIVE WITH THIS FOR THE REST OF
THEIR LIVES.
>>> NO DOUBT.
I DON'T KNOW HOW THE PARENTS
RECOVER.
AS A PARENT I DON'T KNOW HOW
YOU RECOVER.
>>> COMING UP.
YOU ARE LOOKING AT HOBOKEN,
NEW JERSEY THE HOME. BROTHER
RYAN LANZA AND PLUS WORD IS
BREAKING ABOUT THE SHOOTER'S
MENTAL CONDITION.
WE HAVE THE DETAILS AND STAY
WITH US.
FOR THE CONTINUING DEVELOP AMS
AS THEY COME IN THE FOX NEWS
CHANNEL.
♪
[ engine revs ]
[ Male Announcer ]
OH WHAT FUN IT IS TO RIDE.
GET THE MERCEDES-BENZ
ON YOUR WISH LIST
AT THE WINTER EVENT GOING ON
NOW THROUGH DECEMBER 31ST.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
E350 FOR $579 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] WHILE YOU'RE
GETTING READY FOR THE HOLIDAYS,
WE'RE GETTING READY FOR YOU.
TIS THE SEASON.
FOR FOOD, FOR FAMILY,
AND NOW, SOMETHING EXTRA --
FOR YOU.
18 CHILDREN PRONOUNCED DEAD AT
THE SCHOOL AND TWO PRONOUNCED
DEAD AT THE HOSPITALS AND SIX
ADULTS PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE
SCHOOL.
THE SHOOTER IS DECEASED IN THE
>>> POLICE TRY TO PEACE
TOGETHER WHAT MADE 20 YEAR OLD
ADAM LANZA OPEN FIRE IN A
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL TODAY HIS
24 YEAR OLD BROTHER RYAN IS IN
POLICE CUSTODY BEING
QUESTIONED AT THIS HOUR.
THEY ARE OUTSIDE OF THE
APARTMENT IN HOBOKEN, NEW
JERSEY.
WHAT IS THE LATEST THAT YOU
ARE HEARING?
>>> JUST DURING THE COMMERCIAL
BREAK THEY WRAPPED UP THE
POLICE TAPE AND IT IS
GENERALLY A QUIET SCENE BEHIND
ME AND A VERY DIFFERENT SCENE
HERE AND PART OF THAT
CONFUSION LIKELY STEMMED FROM
THE FACT THAT RYAN LANZA ID
WAS FOUND ON ADAM LANZA.
YOU MENTIONED THAT HE IS
SPEAKING WITH POLICE.
THAT IS THE CASE.
HE IS NOT CONSIDERED A SUSPECT
NEITHER HE OR HIS GIRL FRIEND.
THEY ROLLED UP HERE EARLIER
THIS AFTERNOON AND A
RELIRADIABLE SOURCE SAID THEY
SAW POLICE SURROUNDING THE
BUILDING AND RYAN WAS HAND
CUFF TAKEN AWAY.
HE WAS DETERMINED NOT TO BE A
SUSPECT HOWEVER.
THERE WERE ALL THE SORTS OF
CONFLICTING REPORTS.
THEY THOUGHT SOMEONE WAS
MURDERED INSIDE OF THE
APARTMENT BUILDING BEHIND ME
OR THE FATHER.
THE FATHER IS COOPERATING WITH
THE FBI AND THEY ARE REALLY
TALKING TO THE FAMILY MEMBERS,
WE ARE LEARNING THAT ADAM
LANZA LIKELY HAD SOME FORM OF
AUTISM AND A PERMANENT
DISORDER.
BACK TO YOU.
>>> IS IT TRUE THAT RYAN HAD
NOT SPOKEN WITH ADAM IN TWO
YEARS,?
>>> WELL, SEAN I CAN TELL YOU
WE HEARD THE REPORTS, BUWE
HAVE NOT BEEN ABLE TO CONFIRM.
>>> THARCHING YOU.
AND IN THE AFTER MATH OF
TODAY'S TRAGEDY THERE WERE
REPORTS EARLIER THIS YEAR THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IMPLEMENTED SAFETY PROCEDURES
AND SO WHAT HAPPENED AND WHAT
ELSE CAN SCHOOLS DO TO PREVENT
INCIDENTS FROM HAPPENING IN
THE FUTURE?
JOINING ME IS DIRECTOR OF SAFE
HAVENS INTERNATIONAL.
I WAS PEEKING TO FRIENDS OF
MINE THAT ARE IN THE
EDUCATIONAL WORLD AND THEY ARE
VERY CLEAR, THIS SCHOOL WENT
ABOVE AND BEYOND TO GET BOO
SCHOOL, YOU HAD TO BE
IDENTIFIED, AND THEN BUZZED
IN.
AND IT SEEMS LIKE IN THIS
CASE.
THEY WERE DOING EVERYTHING
RIGHT, WHAT WOULD BE THE NEXT
STEP?
>>> SURE, THANKS FOR HAVING ME
ON.
AND WANT EXPRESS CONDOLENCES
TO THE COMMUNITY AND FAMILY.
I AM HEARING A NUMBER OF
INDICATIONS OF GOOD THINGS
THAT WERE IN PLACE IN THE
SCHOOL.
BUSECURITY IS ONLY STRONG AS
YOUR WEAKEST LINK.
YOU BUZZ THEM AND SCREEN THEM,
WE ARE COMMONLIED TO TEST
SECURITY AND CAN BREACH
SECURITY AND WE HAVE TO HAVE
GOOD TECHNOLOGY AND WE HAVE
EXCELLENT TECHNOLOGY TODAY AND
MAKE SURE WE WHAT WE
KNOW ABOUT HOW PEOPLE CAN BE
TRAINED TO DETECT SUBTLE SIGNS
OF DANGER.
>>> DOES THAT MEAN.
>>> NO APPROACH IS FOOL PROOF.
>>> THAT'S THE POINT.
THE SON OF A TEACHER AT THE
SCHOOL WOULD BE SOMEBODY WHO
WOULD PROBABLY BE LET IN AND
YOU WOULDN'T KNOW AND THIS IS
IT A TOWN OF 27,000.
WELL-TO-DO COMMUNITY.
WALK IN AND GET FRISKED.
IS ANOTHER STEP THAT EVERY
COOL HAS ARMED GUARDS.
THEY CAN GET IN THERE FAIRLY
EARLY.
>>> THERE ARE OTHER TECH
TECHNIQUES THAT CAN BE USED .
WE HAVE HAD SHOOTINGS IN THE
SCHOOLS WITH METAL DETECTORS.
THERE ARE LIMITS TO THE
TECHNIQUES.
BUTHERE ARE THINGS IN TERMS OF
TRAINING OF STAFF AND PATTERN
MATCHING AND RECOGNITION AND
BASED AND STAFF IS TRAINED TO
PICK UP ON SUBTLE DIFFERENCES
WE SEE IT WHEN WE BUZZ IN THE
SCHOOLS TO TEST THEM.
I HAVE BEEN STOPPED BECAUSE
THEY DETECT SOMETHING IS NOT
RIGHT TO USE ABOUT THE STORE
TORE TO GET IN.
IF THE PERSON IS NORMALLY
COMING AND GOING FROM THE
SCHOOL IT WOULD BE UNREALISTIC
TO EXPECT THEY WOULD NOT BUZZ
THE SCHOOL INFORM WE'LL NOT
KNOW UNTIL THERE IS
INVESTIGATION .
A LOT OF SCHOOLS AND
ORGANIZATIONS PUT IN GOOD
TECHNOLOGY BUDON'T NECESSARILY
BACK TUP WITH GOOD TRAINING.
THE HUMAN BRAIN IS IT THE
GREATEST DEFENSE MECHANISM AND
STUR VIVAL MECHANISM KNOWN TO
MANKIND ACCORDING TO A
COLLEAGUE I RESPECT GREATLY.
HE'S RIGHT.
IF WE PROGRAM THE BRAIN AND
TEACH PEOPLE THERE ARE A
NUMBER OF INCIDENTS THAT HAVE
BEEN STOPPED THROUGH
TECHNIQUES.
BUNOTHING IS 100%.
>>> THANK YOU, SIR.
COMING UP NEXT.
WE ARE CONTINUING TO GET
DETAILS.
HIS BROTHER IS IN CUSTODY AND
PROVIDING CRUCIAL INFORMATION
ABOUT THE GUNMAN'S MENTAL
CONDITION.
WE'LL HAVE MORE ON THAT COMING
UP TODAY'S TRAGEDY REMINDS OF
COLUMBINE.
WE'LL SPEAK TO A FATHER WHO
LOST HIS DAUGHTER.
AND OFFERS THOUGHT TOTS
FAMILIES THAT LOST EVERYTHING
TODAY
THE SHOOTING APPEARS TO HAVE
STOPPED AND THE SCHOOL IS IN
LOCK DOWN.
THE Capital One
Cash Rewards Card
GIVES YOU 1% CASH BACK
ON ALL PURCHASES,
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS.
AND EVERYONE...BUT HER
LIKES 50% MORE CASH.
BUT I'M UPPING MY GAME.
DO YOU WANT A CANDY CANE?
YES!
DO YOU WANT THE PUPPY?
DO YOU WANT A TRICYCLE?
YES!
DO YOU WANT
50 PERCENT MORE CASH?
NO!
♪
FESTIVE.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE Capital One
Cash Rewards Card
GIVES YOU
1% CASH BACK
ON EVERY
PURCHASE
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS
ON THE CASH YOU EARN.
IT'S THE CARD FOR PEOPLE
WHO LIKE MORE CASH.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
[ Male Announcer ]
BORN FROM THE ELEMENTS.
♪
DESTINED TO TAKE THEM OVER.
THE UCONNECT COMMAND CENTER
WITH SIRIUS XM SATELLITE RADIO
IN THE NEW 2013 RAM 1500.
ENGINEERED TO MOVE HEAVEN
AND EARTH.
GUTS. GLORY.
RAM.
LIKE SAY, GAS STATION SUSHI.
CHEAP IS GOOD.
AND SUSHI, GOOD.
BUT CHEAP SUSHI, NOT SO GOOD.
IT'S LIKE THAT SUPER-LOW RATE
ON NOT ENOUGH CAR INSURANCE.
PRETTY SKETCHY.
♪
AND THEN THERE ARE
THE GOOD DECISIONS.
LIKE ESURANCE.
THEIR COVERAGE COUNSELOR TOOL
HELPS YOU CHOOSE
THE RIGHT COVERAGE FOR YOU
AT A GREAT PRICE.
[ stomach growls ]
WITHOUT FEELING QUEASY.
THAT'S INSURANCE
FOR THE MODERN WORLD.
ESURANCE.
NOW BACKED BY ALLSTATE.
CLICK OR CALL.
A BODY AT REST
TENDS TO STAY AT REST...
WHILE A BODY IN MOTION
TENDS TO STAY IN MOTION.
STAYING ACTIVE CAN ACTUALLY
EASE ARTHRITIS SYMPTO.
BUT IF YOU HAVE ARTHRITIS,
STAYING ACTIVE
CAN BE DIFFICULT.
PRESCRIPTION CELEBREX
CAN HELP RELIEVE ARTHRITIS PAIN
SO YOUR BODY
CAN STAY IN MOTION.
BECAUSE JUST ONE
200MG CELEBREX A DAY
CAN PROVIDE 24 HOUR RELIEF
FOR MANY WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND INFLAMMATION.
PLUS, IN CLINICAL STUDIES,
CELEBREX IS PROVEN TO IMPROVE
DAILY PHYSICAL FUNCTION
SO MOVING IS EASIER.
CELEBREX CAN BE TAKEN WITH
OR WITHOUT FOOD.
AND IT'S NOT A NARCOTIC.
YOU AND YOUR DOCTOR
SHOULD BALANCE THE BENETS
WITH THEISKS.
ALL PRESCRIPTION NSAIDS,
LIKE CELEBREX, IBUPROFEN,
NAPROXEN, AND MELOXICAM
HAVE THE SAME
CARDIOVASCULAR WARNING.
THEY ALL MAY INCREASE
THE CHANCE
OF HEART ATTACK OR STROKE,
WHICH CAN LEAD TO DEATH.
THIS CHANCE INCREASES
IF YOU HAVE HEART DISEASE
RISK FACTORS
SUH AS HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE
OR WHEN NSAIDS ARE TAKEN
FOR LONG PERIODS.
NSAIDS, INCLUDING CELEBREX,
INCREASE THE CHANCE OF SERIOUS
SKIN OR ALLERGIC REACTIONS
OR STOMACH A INTESTINE
PROBLEMS,
SUCH AS BLEEDING AND CERS,
WHICH CAN OCCUR WITHOUT WARNING
AND MAY CAUSE DEATH.
PATIENTS ALSO TAKING ASPIRIN
AND THE ELDEY
ARE AT INCRSED RISK FOR
STOCH BLEEDING AND ULCERS.
DO NOT TAKE CELEBREX IF YOU'VE
HAD AN ASTHMA ATTACK, HIVES,
OR OTHER ALLERGIES TO ASPIRIN,
NSAIDS OR SULFONAMIDES.
GET HELP RIGHTWAY IF YOU HAVE
SWELNG OF THE FACE OR THROAT,
OR TROUBLE BREATHING.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
YOUR MEDICAL HISTORY
AND FIND AN ARTHRITIS TREATMENT
FOR YOU.
VISIT CELEBREX.COM AND ASK
YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT CELEBREX.
FOR A BODY IN MOTION.
>>> WE HEARD GUN SHOTS AND THE
GYM TEACHER DIRECTED US TO
STAY AGAINST THE WALL AND
EVERYONE STARTED PANICKING AND
THEN POLICEMEN CAME IN AND
THEY JUST LIKED IF HE WAS IN
HERE?
BUT THEN WE HAD TO CLIMB IN
THE CLOSEST.
WE HEARD MORE GUN SHOTS AND
THE AMBULANCE CAME AND THEN
THE POLICEMEN TOLD US TO RUN
OUT OF THE BUILD GO TO THE
FIRE DEPARTMENT.
>>> ONE LITTLE GIRL'S
FRIGHTENING ACCOUNT OF WHAT
HAPPENED IN SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AND THE COUNTRY MOURNS THE
TRAGEDY.
IT IS NOT THE FIRST SCHOOL
SHOOTING THAT THE NATION HAS
HAD TO DEAL WITH.
RACHEL WAS KILLED IN THE
COLUMBINE HIGH SCHOOL MASS
CURE.
DARRYL, AS A PARENT, ALL I CAN
THINK OF TODAY IS THESE
PARENTS OUT BUYING CHRISTMAS
GIFTS.
KIDS AT THIS AGE EXCITED ABOUT
SANTA CLAUS AND CHRISTMAS IS
IT COMING, AND NOW PLANNING A
FUNERAL AND NO CHRISTMAS OR
BIRTHDAYS, HOW DO YOU RECOVER?
YOU HAVE BEEN THROUGH THIS.
>>> WELL, THERE IS NOTHING YOU
CAN TELL A PARENT THAT LOST
THE CHILD.
THEY NEED THEIR FRIENDS AND
FAMILY.
IN OUR CASE, WE MADE CHOICES.
WE MADE THE CHOICE NOT TO BE
ANGRY AND BETTER BUT TO
CELEBRATE RACHEL'S LIFE AND
TODAY WE HAVE THE LARGEST
SCHOOL TRAINING PROGRAMS AND
REACH THREE MILLION STUDENTS A
YEAR WITH RACHEL'S CHALLENGE
AND TRAIN OVER 300,000
CHILDREN AND SCHOOL 500
SUICIDES PREVENTED.
A LOT OF THE ANSWERS ARE LONG
TERM.
THEY ARE NOT JUST A KNEE JERK
REACTION OR MORE LAWS AND
REGULATIONS .
BUT WE HAVE TO BE A KINDER
NATION AND TAKE TIME TO LISTEN
TO ONE ANOTHER AND BE ROLE
MODELS IN THESE KIDS.
AND YOU ARE ACTIVE AND IN YOUR
HEALING, AM I INTERPERTING IT
RIGHT.
MY SON CRAIG WAS IN THE
LIBRARY AND HE CAME WITHIN A
SPLIT SECOND OF BEING KILLED.
AND I WOULD HAVE LOST TWO
CHILDREN.
MY HEART GOES OUT TO THE
PARENTS WHO LOST THE CHILDREN
AND DEALING WITH THE TRAUMA OF
THE CHILDREN GOING THROUGH.
AND COUNSELING AND A THEY NEED
A LOT OF LOVE AND ATTENTION.
OUR HEARTS AND PRAYERS GO OUT
TO ALL OF THESE WONDERFUL POEM
THAT LOST CHILDREN TONIGHT.
>>> WHEN DUTHINK YOU STARTED
TO RECOVER.
IT TAKES A LONG TIME TO HEAL
THIS PAIN.
HOW LONG DID IT TAKE YOU TO
TURN THE CORNER A LITTLE BIT.
>>> HONESTLY, YOU NEVER
TOTALLY HEAL.
THERE IS ALWAYS A HOLE IN YOUR
HEART WHEN YOU LOSE A CHILD.
WE HAVE CHILDREN AND GRAND
CHILDREN.
BUT THERE IS ALWAYS A MISSING
GAP THERE WITH RACHEL.
IT DOES -- YOU GO THROUGH
STAGES OF SHOCK ASK DISBELIEF
AND ANGER AND WHOLE GAMUT OF
EMOTIONS AND THE INITIAL STING
IN THE FIRST TWO OR THREE
YEARS BEGINS TO WEAR OFF AND
YOU NEVER LOSE IT COMPLETEY
LOO.
AND CELEBRATING THEIR LIVES
AND FOCUS ON THAT AND NOT
DIRECT THE ANGER TOWARD THE
SHOOTER AND EVEN FRACTIS AND
THIS IS NOT A TIME FOR THOSE
PARENT TO HEAR BUT WE CHOSE TO
FORGIVE AND SOME PEOPLE CAN'T
DO THAT.
FORGIVENESS AND FOCUSING ON
THE POSITIVE IN YOUR CHILD'S
LIFE GOES A LONG WAY TO
HELPING.
DARRYL, SORRY ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED TO YOUR DAUGHTER AND
THANKS FOR SHARING YOUR
EXPERIENCE AND HELPING MORE
PEOPLE.
NAND THE SHOTTER MAY HAVE
SUFFERED FROM A PERSONALITY
DISORDER.
JOINING ME NOW ABOUT THE
SHOOTER'S MENTAL CONDITION.
WE HAVE DOCTORS HERE PART OF
THE FOX MEDICAL TEEM.
WE HEARD PERSONALITY DISORDER.
I HEARD THE TERM AUTISM AND
ASBERGER'S SYNDROME.
OBVIOUS LOW THE KID AT THIS
AGE SHOOTING HIS MOTHER AND
GOING INTO SHOOT WITH ABANDON
ALL OF THESE KIDS.
WOULD ANY OF THOSE CONDITIONS
TELL YOU THAT CAN HAPPEN?
>>> HE IS OUT OF TOUCH WITH
REALITY.
IF HE HAD ASBERGER'S HE MAY
HAVE HAD ONGOING MELT DOWNS
ASSOCIATED WITH VIOLENT
BEHAVIOR.
IT IS POSSIBLE HE WAS ON
DICATION AND IT WAS NOT
WORKING AND HE DIDN'T HAVE
EMPATHY AND HAD SOCIAL
PROBLEMS.
BUT THAT DOESN'T EXPLAIN
EVERYTHING AND GIVEN THE AGE
OF 20, THAT HE BECAME PSCOTIC
AND HE HAD A DELUSIONAL SYSTEM
THAT LED TO A HEINOUS CRIME.
>>> IS IT ALWAYS A MEDICAL
CONDITION.
IF SOMEONE IS DISCONNECTED
FROM ROLIT AND NO SIM THEE OR
CONSCIOUSNESS AND NO SOUL,
THERE IS HUMAN EVIL, I MEAN
SOMEBODY CAN KILL INNOCENT
CHILDREN LIKE IT SEEMS TO ME
THAT IS IT EVIL.
>>> I DON'T KNOW WHAT THE
DOCTOR'S OPINION IS ON I DON'T
LET POEM OFF OF THE HOOK AND
SAY IT IS IT A MENAL
CONDITION.
IT IS AN ISSUE OF EVIL HERE AS
WELL.
>>> HERE'S WHAT I THINK >>>
THE COMMON DENOMINATOR.
LACK OF EMPATHY.
YOU CAN'T WALK UP TO THE CHILD
AND KILL IT AND SIGH THE CHILD
FALL TO THE GROUND OR SLUMP
OVER AND MAINTAINING ANY
EMPATHY.
WHY CAN YOU LOSE HUMAN
YOU CAN BE DELUSIONAL AND
WORKING ON A DELUSIONAL
SYSTEM.
BUT YOU COULD BE IF YOU THINK
I DO THIS I SAVE THE WHOLE
WORLD.
AND THAT IS ONE LEVEL.
AND SURE PERSONALITY DISORDERS
CAN DO THIS AND OTHER
CONDITIONS LIKE DRUG ABUSE
COMBINED WITH EITHER A MOOD
DISORDER OR PERSONALITY OR ALL
THREE.
BUT IS IT A MENTAL ILLNESS.
OF COURSE IT IS.
THAT LACK OF EMPATHY DOESN'T
COME FROM NO WHERE.
AND IN 20 YEARS SEAN I NEVER
FOUND ANYBODY WHO DOES
ANYTHING LIKE THIS THAT BEEN
THROUGH HELL IN A WAY THAT
CREATES MENTAL ILLNESS.
>>> THIS IS IMPORTANT I THINK.
FIRST RESPHONDERS ARE GOING TO
NEED COUNSELING AND THE
PARENTS.
AS A PARENT THEY ARE GOING TO
NEED COUNSELING.
AND STUNES ARE GOING TO BE
TRAUMATIZED AND POST TRAUMATIC
STRESS AND DIFFERENT AND ALL
LIKE WANT TROOPS GO THROUGH.
WHAT DO YOU EXPECT TO HAPPEN
TO THE PEOPLE IN >>> THE VET
ADMINISTRATION LOCKED AT 600
KIDS WHO WERE, THANK GOD
WEREN'T KILLED WILL HAVE
STRESS DISORDER AND THEY WILL
BE AGGRESSIVE, SAD OR NOT
FEELING HELP AND NOT SLEEPING
WELL.
IT CAN LAST FOR MONTHS AND
MONTHS IF NOT YEARS.
COGNITIVE THERAPY HELPS.
THANK YOU.
AND COMING UP NEXT.
A FORMER RESIDENT OF THAT
TIGHT KNIT COMMUNITY IS
STANDING BY.
THAT IS COMING UP NEXT RIGHT
HERE ON HANNITY.
[ Male Announcer ]
RED LOBSTER'S
HITTING THE STREETS
TO TELL REAL PEOPLE ABOUT
OUR NEW 15 UNDER $15 MENU.
OH MY GOODNESS!
OH MY GOSH,
THIS LOOKS AMAZING!
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR NEW MAINE STAYS!
15ENTREES UNDER $15,
SEAFOOD, CHICKEN AND MORE!
OOTHE TILAPIAWITH ROASTEDEGETAB!
I'M ACTUALLY LOOKING AT
THE WO GRILLED CHICKEN
WITH PORTOBELLO WINE SAUCE.
AT PORK CHOP
WAS GREAT!
NO MORE
FAST FOOD FRIDAY'S!
WE'RE GOING TO GO
TO RED LOBSTER.
YEP.
[ Male Announcer ]
COME TRY OUR NEW MENU
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
SALAD, SANDWICHES, AND MORE.
YOU WON'T TAKE OUR FUTURE.
AIDS AFFECTS US ALL.
EVEN BABIES.
CHEVRON IS WORKING TO STOP
MOTHER-TO-CHILD TRANSMISSION.
OUR EMPLOYEES AND THEIR FAMILIES
ARE PART OF THE FIGHT.
AND WE'RE WINNING.
AT CHEVRON NIGERIA, WE HAVEN'T
HAD A REPORTED CASE IN 12EARS.
AIDS IS STRONG.
BUT WE ARE STRONGER.
AND AIDS...
♪
AIDS IS GOING TO LOSE.
Is bigger than we think ...
Sometimelike the flu.fer fromE.
With aches, fever and chills-
the flu's a really big deal.
So why treat it like
it's a little cold?
Thks differently
than over-the-counter
remedies.
Prescription TAMIFLU attacks
the flu virus at its source.
So don't wait. Call your
doctor right away.
TAMIFLU is prescription
medicine for treating the flu
in adults and children
one year and older
whose flu symptoms started
within the last two days.
Before taking TAMIFLU tell your
doctor if you're pregnant,
nursing. have serious
health conditions,
or take other medicines.
If you develop an allergic
reaction, a severe rash,
or signs of unusual behavior,
stop taking TAMIFLU and call
your doctor immediately.
Children and adolescents in
particular may be at an
increased risk
of seizures, confusion
or abnormal behavior.
The most common
side effects are
mild to moderate nausea
and vomiting.
The flu comes on fast,
so ask your
doctor about TAMIFLU.
Prescription for flu.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO HANUTY AS
WE CONTINUED THE REPORT ON THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
WE GO BACK TO CONNECTICUT
WHERE A RESIDENT OF THAT TIGHT
KNIT COMMUNITY IS JOINING US.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US.
>>> YOU'RE WELCOME, SEAN.
>>> TELL US ABOUT THE PRAYER
VIGIL AND INFORMATION YOU
MIGHT HAVE PICKED UP TODAY.
>>> THE PRAYER VIGIL WAS
ABSOLUTE LOW BEAUTIFUL.
IT WAS JUST UNBELIEVABLE HOW
MANY PEOPLE SHOWED UP AT THIS
CHURCH AND PEOPLE OUTSIDE AND
JUST CRYING.
AND LOVE AND HUGGING EACH
OTHER.
IT WAS ABSOLUTELY WONDERFUL.
>>> YEAH.
>>> I AM STOW GLAD I ATTENDED
IT.
>>> I AM GLAD YOU DID AS WELL.
I KNOW THE COMMUNITY WILL NODE
A LOT OF HEALING.
IT IS IT A VERY SMALL
TIGHT-KNIT TOWN.
27,000 PEOPLE AND KNOWN AS A
SAFE NEIGHBORHOOD, CORRECT?
>>> ABSOLUTELY.
THERE IS NO CRIME IN NEWTOWN.
THIS IS IT JUST AN ISOLATED
INCIDENT AND HE WAS NOT EVEN A
RESIDENT HERE.
HE WAS FROM NEW JERSEY AND HE
USED TO LIVE THERE.
>>> HIS MOTHER LIVED NEARBY
AND SHE WAS KILLED BEFORE HE
WENT ON THE SCHOOL RAMPAGE.
>>> UNBELIEVABLE.
IT IS VERY, VERY SAD.
>>> WERE THERE PARENTS AND
SOME OF THE KIDS FROM THE
SCHOOL AT THE VIGIL, MA'AM?
NYES, YES, CRYING.
JUST HUGGING THEIR PARENTS AND
CRYING.
AND I WAS HUGGING MY GRAND
DAUGHTER AND MY DAUGHTER, IT
WAS JUST THARCHINGFUL THAT WE
ARE ALIVE.
>>> THANK YOU, FOR SHARE THAG
WITH US.
WHEN WE COME BACK OUR GOOD
FRIEND BO DEDLE IS WITH US.
AND YOU WILL HEAR WHAT ONE
FIRST GRADE TEACHER TOLD HER
STUDENTS WHEN THEY WERE
WAITING FOR THE POLICE TO
ARRIVE.
THAT EMOTIONAL STORY IS COMING
UP NEXT.
(SIREN)
♪
[ engine revs ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THE MERCEDES-BENZ WINTER EVENT
IS BACK,
WITH THE PERFECT VEHICLE
THAT'S JUST RIGHT FOR YOU,
NO MATTER WHICH LIST YOU'RE ON.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
C250 FOR $349 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
>> I AM THINKING AS A SIX OR
SEN YEAR OLD WHAT ARE YOUR
THOUGHTS?
I AM THINKING I HAVE TO BE
THEIR PARENT AND HAVE TO TELL
THEM AND I SAID I NEED YOU TO
KNOW THEY LOVE YOU ALL VERY
MUCH.
AND THAT IT IS GOING TO BE
OKAY.
I THOUGHT THAT WAS THE LAST
THING WE WERE GOING TO HEAR
AND I THOUGHT WE WERE ALL
GOING TO DIE .
I DON'T KNOW IF THAT IS OKAY,
TEACHERS, BUT I WANTED THEM TO
KNOW I LOVED THEM AND THAT
WOULD BE ONE OF THE LAST
THINGS THEY HEARD AND NOT THE
GUN FIRE IN THE HALLWAY.
IT IS HORRIBLE, HORRIBLE.
>> THAT WAS A FIRST GRADE
TEACHER IN SANY HOOK
ELEMENTARY THINKING ABOUT HER
UNBELIEVABLE DAY AND LIKELY TO
HEAR MORE STORIES AS THE
TRAGEDY UNFOLDS .
HERE IS DR. MICHAEL BODEN.
FORMER NYPD DETECTIVE BO.
AND PSYCHE THERAPIST IS HERE
WITH US.
TUNES AND TEACHERS AND BO HAS
SEWN A LOT IN HIS DAY.
THEY WILL BE DEALING WITH A
LOT.
>> IT IS EXTRAORDINARILY
TRAUMATIZING.
NTO THE PARTNERS THE MOST?
>> RIGHT.
GETTING HEALING IS MOST
IMPORTANT.
WHAT PARENTS CAN DO FOR THE
CHILDREN.
GET THEM HOME SO THEY ARE IN A
COMFORTABLE SITUATION AND
PROVIDE THEM WITH STRUCTURE.
STRUCTURE IS VERY COMFORTING
AND NOT OVERWHELM THEM WITH
TOO MUCH INFORMATION BUT BE A
PERSON .
>> WOULD YOU HAVE THEM GO TO
VIGILS AND FUNERALS OR DEPENDS
ON THE KID.
>> IT DEPENDS ON THE KID AND
THE SITUATION.
IF THEIR CHILD LOST A GOOD
FRIEND IT MIGHT BE GOOD TO
TAKE THEM TO THE FUNERAL.
IT WOULD BE OKAY.
AND THEY DON'T GET FRIGHTENED
AND IT IS OKAY TO HAVE A
BROADRANGE OF E.
- EMOTION .
>> I HAVE SIX CHILDREN AND
1984, WE HAD THE PALM SUNDAY
MASSCURE.
THIS MAN WENT IN A HOUSE AND
SHOT AND KILLED 10 KIDS.
THEY WERE ALL SITTING AROUND
AND NO ONE RAN AWAY.
IT IS IT A FREEZE THING.
WHEN SOMEONE IS SYSTEMATICALLY
SHOOTING PEOPLE KIDS FREEZE.
IT IS LIKE THEY WERE ALL 12
AND UNDER.
SIX YORE OLD AND FIVE YORE OLD
AND THESE KIDS WERE ALL
SITTING AROUND AND ALL HAD
SHOTS.
>> YOU SAW TEMPERATURE >>
VIVID IN MY MIND AND THE FIRST
RESPONDERS I AM SURE THAT WAS
HORRIFIC.
10 DAY I SAW AND LARGEST MASS
MURDER IN NEW YORK HISTORY
BEFORE 9/11.
THAT IS BURNED IN MY BRAIN.
I CAN JUST IMAGINE WHAT THIS
WAS.
HOW COME THERE WAS NO
SURVIVORS.
THIS PUNK.
PROBABLY SHOT THEM IN THE HEAD
AND IF HE SHOT BODY SHOTS, WE
WOULD HAVE HAD A LOT MORE
SURVIVORS.
>> DOCTOR, YOU HAVE SEEN MANY.
NI DID THE AUTOPSIES ON THOSE.
>> YOU HAVE SEEN A LOT.
HOW DO YOU KIND OF, I GUESS IT
IS LIKE ANY JOB, YOU HAVE TO
FIND A WAY TO COMPARTMENTALIZE
WHAT YOU ARE WITNESSING OR YOU
DON'T SURVIVE.
>> IN A SENSE, THE DECEEDENTS
ARE OUT OF THE PAIN AND
MISERY.
IT IS IT THE PARTNERS AND
FAMILIES.
THEY ARE GOING THROUGH A STATE
THAT WILL LAST A FEW DAYS
UNTIL THEY GET THEIR BABIES
BACK.
THE SIVENADULTS WILL BE
AUTOPSIED ESPECIALLY THE
PERPETRATOR.
BUT THE CHILDREN HAVE TO BE
EXAMINED AND THEY HAVE
DOCUMENT THE INJURIES ON THE
CHILDREN AND IF THERE ARE
BULLETS IN THE BODIES THEY
HAVE TO BE REMOVED.
TO MATCH IT UP TO THE WEAPONS
AND MAKE SURE THERE WAS NOT A
WEAPON THEY DON'T KNOW ABOUT.
IT TAKES TIME.
>> IT COMES BACK.
AND I HAVE BEEN INVOLVED WITH
THIS SAFE SCHOOL THING AND SEE
SOMETHING NOTIFY.
AND CALL NUMBER THERE.
AND IT IS COMING DOWN.
I GET CALLS IN THE OFFICE.
SCHOOLS NOW ARING FOR OFF DUTY
COPS WITH A GUN.
LET'S BE HONEST IF A GUY HAD A
GUN, HE MIGHT HAVE KILLED SOME
PEOPLE YOU WOULD AT LEAST BE
ABLE TO LIMIT IT.
>> THAT'S WHAT I WANT.
>> THAT'S WHY THEY TARGET
SCHOOL SYSTEMS.
>> IT IS GOING TO COME DOWN TO
IT.
THESE ARE PRECIOUS THINGINGS.
WE'LL PAY FOR A RETIRED COP
WITH A GUN SO ONE OF THESE
PUNKS COME IN.
HE WILL NOT HAVE FREE WILL.
IF HE HAD MORE BULLETS AND
TIME, HE COULD HAVE KILLED
MORE UNTIL THOSE COPS GOT
THERE.
IT IS HORRIFIC.
>> I THINK WE ARE HEADED THERE
ESPECIALLY COPS IN NEW YORK.
>> I THINK IT IS IT GREAT.
BUT THE GOOD NEWS, KIDS ARE