HI,
I'M Ensure Clear...
Clear, HUH?
I'M NOT JUICE OR FANCY WATER.
I'VE GOTINE GRAMS OF PROTEIN.
THAT'S THREE TIMES MORE THAN ME!
[ Female Announcer ]
Ensure Clear.
NINE GRAMS PROTEIN. ZERO FAT.
IN BLUEBERRY/POMEGRANATE
AND PEACH.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME R CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
>>Megyn: THANKS FOR WATCHING,
EVERYONE, OUR COVERAGE CONTINUES
NOW.
>> MOURNERS HERE IN THE
SHATTERED NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
TOWN OF 27,000 HELD THE FIRST
TWO FUNERALS FOR THE YOUNG
VICTIMS ON FRIDAY'S SCHOOL
MASSACRE.
THE FIRST OF 20 FUNERALS FOR
CHILDREN.
AFTER THE WORST GRADE SCHOOL
MASSACRE OUR COUNTRY HAS EVER
SEEN.
I AM BILL HEMMER HERE FOR
SHEPARD SMITH.
THE VIGILS AND MEMORIALS ARE
HEMMED FOR THE 26 PEOPLE FOR
THOSE WHO DIED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
PRESIDENT OBAMA CONSOLED THE
FAMILIES AND SURVIVORS TELLING A
WEEPING CROWD THAT HE WILL USE
ALL THE POWERS HIS OFFICE CAN
BEAR TO KEEP SOMETHING LIKE THIS
FROM HAPPENING ONCE AGAIN.
>> THE INVESTIGATION CONTINUES.
THE TIGHT KNIT COMMUNITY AND
EVERYONE ACROSS THE COUNTRY
TRYING TO UNDERSTAND THE "WHY."
WHY A 20-YEAR-OLD YOUNG MAN WHO
WAS SMART ENOUGH TO TAKE COLLEGE
COURSES AT THE AGE OF 16 COULD
COMMIT SUCH A HEINOUS CRIME?
WHY A WELL-TO-DO MOTHER WOULD
HAVE A COLLECTION OF HEAVY DUTY
WEAPONS WHICH POLICE SAY HER SON
USED TO SHOOT HER IN THE HEAD,
FOUR TIMES, THAT MORNING, IN HER
PAJAMAS BEFORE HE TOOK THE SAME
GUNS TO THE SCHOOL TO KILL
INNOCENT CHILDREN.
THE GUNS WERE HER WAY TO
CONNECTING WITH HER TROUBLED
SON.
>> SHE WAS TRYING TO BOND, FIND
WAYS TO BOND WITH HIM AND SHE
TOLD ME THE GUNS, SHE WOULD TAKE
THEM SHOOTING BECAUSE THAT WAS A
WAY A SINGLE MOM COULD RELATE TO
HER SON.
SHE WOULD TAKE HIM OUT SHOOTING.
>>Reporter: FAMILY AND FRIENDS
DESCRIBE THE SHOOTER AS A
SOCIALLY AWKWARD LONER BUT THEY
DO NOT KNOW WHY HE SNAPPED.
WE START THE HOUR WITH OUR TEAM
FOX COVERAGE WITH JONATHAN HUNT,
BACK, LIKE, WITH ME NEAR THE
SCHOOL.
WHERE IS THE INVESTIGATION
TODAY?
>>Jonathan: IT IS MOVING
SLOWLY.
ACCORDING TO LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE, METHODALLY.
THERE ARE TWO MAIN LOCATIONS
THEY ARE INVESTIGATING.
THE FIRST, OF COURSE, IS THE
SCHOOL WHERE THE 20 CHILDREN AND
SIX WOMEN STAFF MEMBERS ALL DIED
IN THE BLAZE OF GUNFIRE ON
FRIDAY.
THE SECOND LOCATION, ADAM
LANZA'S MOTHER HOUSE, WHERE HE
KILLED HIS OWN MOTHER SHOOTING
HER SEVERAL TIMES IN THE HEAD.
HE THEN TOOK THE WEAPONS TO THE
SCHOOL AND CARRIED OUT THE
MASSACRE.
IT IS A VERY DIFFICULT
INVESTIGATION IF SO MANY REASONS
BUT LIEUTENANT VANCE SAYS FOR
THE SAKE OF THE PEOPLE OF THIS
TOWN, THE PEOPLE OF STATE, THE
PEOPLE OF THE UNITED STATES,
THEY WILL GET TO THE BOTTOM OF
ALL OF THIS.
>> THE ANSWERS FOR THE VICTIMS
AND THE VICTIMS AND THE FAMILIES
AND THE PEOPLE OF CONNECTICUT,
THEY WANT A CLEAR PICTURE
EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
MANY TIMES, I HAVE SAID,
ARE MANY PEOPLE, INCLUDING FIRST
RESPONDERS AND TOWN RESIDENTS
AND INCLUDING PEOPLE IN THIS
AUDIENCE THAT IS BROKEN HEARTS
OVER THIS.
WE ARE GOING TO DO EVERYTHING
THAT IT TAKES TO ENSURE WE
UNCOVER EVERY BIT OF EVIDENCE,
THAT WE EXAMINE EVERY BIT OF IT
AND WE CONDUCT AS MANY
INTERVIEWS WITH EVERYONE WE NEED
TO, TO PAINT A CLEAR PICTURE
EXACTLY HOW AND WHY THIS TRAGEDY
OCCURRED.
>>Jonathan: HE PROMISES
ANSWERS BUT ADMITTING AT THE
SAME TIME THAT THE ANSWERS ARE
GOING TO TAKE A LONG TIME.
>>Reporter: THE FIREHOUSE,
JONATHAN, THIS IS WHERE THE KIDS
RAN.
THE ONES WHO WERE ABLE TO GET
OUT OF SCHOOL 100 YARDS DOWN THE
DRIVE FROM THE SCHOOL.
YOU WONDER ABOUT THE SURVIVORS
AND HOW THEY ARE COPING, TWO
FUNERALS TODAY.
THAN I HAD A FASCINATING
CONVERSATION WITH ONE OF A LARGE
TEAM OF CLINICAL PSYCHOLOGIST
WHOSE HAVE BEEN BROUGHT IN HERE
TO DO THAT, TO TALK TO THE
SURVIVING CHILDREN, TO TALK THEM
THROUGH WHAT THEY WENT THROUGH,
TO HELP THEM COPE WITH THE
PRESENT AND, OF COURSE, TO LEARN
FOR THE FUTURE, TO TRY TO GET
THEM THROUGH THIS AS BEST THEY
CAN.
SHE SAY IT IS A DIFFICULT
PROCESS AND THE CHILDREN, AS
MUCH AS ANYTHING, ARE THE MOST
IMPORTANT ONES IN HELPING EACH
OTHER.
>> ALL THE MOMENTS STANDOUT.
THEY ARE ALL HEARTBREAKING
MOMENTS, WATCHING ONE CHILD COME
IN, A YOUNG BOY COMING IN AND
BEING VERY SHY AND WITHDRAWN AND
NOT WANTING TO TALK TO ANYONE
AND WITH HIS HEAD DOWN AND
HOLDING HIMSELF AND WATCHING TWO
YOUNG SCHOOLMATES, GIRLS, COME
RUSHING OVER TO HIM AND HUGGING
HIM, AND JUST, HE STARTED TO
MELT A LITTLE BIT, AND THEY
BROUGHT HIM OVER TO WHERE THE
TOYS WERE AND THEY WERE TALKING
TO HIM AND IT BROUGHT HIM OUT OF
THE SHELL.
I ALMOST CRIED WITH HOW
BEAUTIFUL I IS THAT HOW CHILDREN
WERE HELPING AND SUPPORTING EACH
OTHER.
>>Jonathan: THE DR. KURIANSKY
HAS WORKED WITH CHILDREN AFTER
THE TSUNAMI AND IN THE WAKE OF
THE EARTHQUAKE OF HAITI WE
COVERED AND SHE SAID THIS IS THE
ONE OF THE MOST IMPORTANT
THINGS, CHILDREN HELPING
CHILDREN.
THE PLEASING BLESSIN HERE IS
THAT CHILDREN ARE VERY
RESILIENT.
>>Reporter: YOU WONDER HOW THE
ADULTS AND PARENTS WILL COPE,
WITH THEM REACHING OUT.
A WEEK IN TOMORROW IS CHRISTMAS
DAY.
AT WHAT POINT DO THE CHILDREN
OUT OF SCHOOL GET BACK TO
SCHOOL?
>>Jonathan: THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT, CLASSES ARE OPEN,
AGAIN TOMORROW.
IN TERMS OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY, ANYONE'S GUESS RIGHT
NOW.
LIEUTENANT VANCE SAID IT REMAINS
VERY OBVIOUSLY A CRIME SCENE BUT
HE ALSO SAID INTERESTINGLY, IT
IS LIKELY TO REMAIN A CRIME
SCENE, IN HIS WORDS, FOR MONTHS.
THEY DO NOT INTENDS TO CLOSE
DOWN THAT AS A SCENE OF THE
INVESTIGATION FOR A VERY LONG
TIME.
IT REMAINS AN OPEN QUESTION
WHETHER SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL WILL EVER BE RE-OPENED.
OBVIOUSLY THERE ARE ARGUMENTS ON
BOTH SIDES AND IT IS A DIFFICULT
QUESTION THAT THE COMMUNITY WILL
HAVE TO GRAPPLE WITH.
>>Jonathan: TERRIFIC REPORT
REPORTING.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA SPOKE OF THE
20 VICTIMS AND SAID THAT GOD HAS
CALLED THEM ALL HOME.
TODAY, FAMILY AND FRIENDS ATTEND
FUNERAL SERVICES FOR SIX
-YEAR-OLD NOAH POZER AND JACK
PINTO.
NOAH WAS CALLED "SMART AS A
WHIP."
HE TURNED SINCE ON THE 20th OF
NOVEMBER.
HIS TWIN SISTER, SHE WAS AT THE
SCHOOL ON THE SAME DAY BUT IN A
DIFFERENT CLOSE ROOM.
SHE IS ALIVE.
YOU CAN SEE FROM JACK'S TATTOOS
HE WAS A BIG FAN OF THE NEW YORK
GIANTS, THE TAR WIDE RECEIVER
WROTE A MESSAGE ON HIS OWN
CLEATS FOR SUNDAY'S GAME READING
JACK PINTO, MY HERO, REST IN
PEACE.
AND NOW, MORE IN NEWTOWN FROM
RICK.
Rick: THESE ARE OBVIOUSLY
HEARTBREAKING AND CHALLENGING
DAYS FOR THE COMMUNITY.
THE WEEKS AND MONTHS AND YEARS
AHEAD WILL REMAIN THAT WAY AS
JONATHAN DISCUSSED, THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL STILL IS
A CRIME SCENE SO THERE ARE
EFFORTS UNDERWAY TO FIND ANOTHER
PLACE FOR THE KIDS TO GO TO
SCHOOL.
BECAUSE POLICE WERE AT THE
SCHOOL TODAY THEY WERE THERE TO
SUPERVISE THE MOVING VANS ROLLED
UP TO MOVE OUT THE FURNITURE AND
DESKS AND OTHER SUPPLIES FROM
THE SCHOOL THAT COULD BE MOVED
TO ANOTHER LOCATION.
THAT LOCATION IS IN A TOWN OF
MONROE ABOUT 15 MILES AWAY WHERE
THE SANDY HOOK SURVIVORS ARE
EXPECTED TO GO BACK TO SCHOOL
LATER THIS WEEK.
YOU MENTION THE TWO FUNERALS
BEING HELD TODAY, TWO
SIX-YEAR-OLD BOYS INCLUDING JACK
PINTO, WHO WAS REMEMBERED HERE
IN NEWTOWN AS LOVING AND A
GIVING SPIRIT AND DETERMINATION,
ALSO NOAH WITH HIS FUNERAL
ATTENDED BY THE GOVERNOR AND
MANY OTHERS INCLUDING HIS TWIN
SISTER AND OLDER SISTER WHO BOTH
ATTENDED SANDY HOOK AND
SURVIVED.
THE FUNERALS WILL STRETCH
THROUGHOUT THE WEEK.
>>Reporter: TWO TODAY.
TWO TOMORROW AND A SERIES AFTER
THAT WE HAVE NEW DETAILS ABOUT
INCREDIBLE ACTS OF HEROISM.
WHAT ARE YOU ABLE TO REPORT
ABOUT THAT NOW?
>>Reporter: MANY OF THE
STORIES ARE COMING FROM THE
CHILDREN WHO SURVIVED THE
SHOOTING IN THAT SCHOOL ON
FRIDAY.
CHILDREN WHO EITHER HID OR RAN
FOR THEIR LIVES.
AMONG THEM STUDENTS OF 27
-YEAR-OLD TEACHER AT THE
SCHOOL.
ACCORDING TO THE NEWSPAPER SHE
HERDED THE 13 CHILDREN INTO A
BATHROOM AND CLASS IT AND WHEN
HE DEMANDED TO TO KNOW WHERE THE
KIDS WERE SHE SAID THEY WERE IN
THE AUDITORIUM BUT SIX KIDS
PANICKED AND TRIED TO RUN AND HE
SHOT THEM AND SHOT THE TEACHER
AND HER ASSISTANT AND THE OTHER
SEVEN KIDS STAYED HIDDEN IN THAT
CLOGS IT OR BATHROOM UNTIL THE
POLICE OFFICERS WERE IN THE
SCHOOL, OPENED THE DOOR, AND
WERE SURPRISED TO SEE SEVEN
PAIRS OF EYES STARING BACK AT
THEM.
>> THANK YOU, RISK, WE WILL BE
IN TOUCH LATER WHEN WE GET MORE
HEADLINES AND MORE INFORMATION
ABOUT MOVING THIS STORY FORWARD.
IT IS OBVIOUS, YOU CAN SEE THE
TENT BEHIND ME, THIS IS A
MAKESHIFT MEMORIAL THAT STARTED
YESTERDAY.
THIS IS AT THE END OF THE 100
YARD ROAD THAT LEADS TO THE
PARKING LOT AND TO THE SCHOOL.
THIS IS AS CLOSE AS ANY REPORTER
OR NOW ANY MEMBER OF THE PUBLIC
CAN GET TO THE SCHOOL.
LATE YESTERDAY, THEY ERECTED 26
CHRISTMAS TREES AND THERE IS A
LINE OF PYLONS TO THE MAIN ROAD
A QUARTER OF A MILE DOWN THE
ROAD WITH CHRISTMAS ORNAMENTS
AND TEDDY BEARS AND FLOWERS HAVE
POURED IN FROM EVERY STATE AND
THAT PROCESS CONTINUES
THROUGHOUT THE DAY.
WE ARE WATCHING THE SCENE.
EARLIER WE WERE AT THE END OF
THE ROAD AND THESE MAKESHIFT
MEMORIALS THAT HAVE BEEN SET UP
THROUGHOUT THE TOWN, THEY WILL
RIP YOUR HEART OUT AS WE FOUND
EARLY TODAY.
>> THIS IS THE CHRISTMAS TREE
THAT IS SET UP IN THE VILLAGE OF
SANDY HOOK WHICH IS A VILLAGE IN
THE GREATER TOWN OF NEWTOWN.
THERE ARE SO MANY POIGNANT
ORNAMENTS AND REMINDERS AND OR
THE -- AND ORNAMENTS AND THIS IS
FOR NOAH, BORN NOVEMBER 20,
2006.
IT GOES ON AND ON THROUGHOUT THE
AREA.
THE LEGO STAND I NOTICED HAS
BEEN SET UP, AND THE CANDLES
THAT WERE BURNING ALL WEEKEND
LONG, EXTINGUISHED NOW BECAUSE
OF THE RAIN OR BECAUSE OF TIME.
THIS CAUGHT MY EYE, STATE POLICE
OF CONNECTICUT.
WRAPPED AROUND A TEDDY BEAR.
THE POLICE BEEN SO WONDERFUL AND
SO PROFESSIONAL AND IT IS AN
INDICATION AND A STRONG NOD TO
THE PEOPLE OF CONNECTICUT THEY
HAVE A LOT TO BE PROUD OF WITH
THE POLICE DEPARTMENT.
YOU CAN SEE THE AREA, IT HAS
GROWN BY THE DAY, THE BALLOONS
AND THE TEDDY BEARS AND THE
WREATHS AND THE FLOWERS AND THIS
CHRISTMAS TREE OVER HERE IT HAS
THE NAMES, IT IS SMALL, JUST
LIKE A CHILD AT THAT AGE, THERE
IS CHASE.
THIS IS DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, THE
PRINCIPAL, A MOTHER OF FIVE, TWO
DAUGHTERS OF HER OWN AND THREE
STEPDAUGHTERS.
AND I SEE JACK PINTO'S NAME OVER
HERE.
AND EMILY PARKER WHOSE FATHER
CAME OUT ON SATURDAY NIGHT AND
HAD SUCH A WONDERFUL TRIBUTE TO
HIS DAUGHTER.
THIS IS THE CENTER OF SANDY
HOOK, FOREVER TO BE REMEMBERED
WE, PRAYERS AND THOUGHTS FOR
THOSE WHO HAVE LEFT US.
FOREVER.
12/14/12 ON THE CALENDAR.
BEHIND ME ARE THE TEDDY BEARS
THAT WILL WOULDED IN.
A GENTLEMAN FROM A CITY COUNCIL
IN FAIRFIELD, THEY CANCELED THE
BENEFIT BECAUSE OF RAIN AND EVEN
AFTER 250 SHOWED UP BRINGING SO
MANY STUFFED ANIMALS THEY FILLED
A VAN AND JUST NOW DROPPED THEM
OFF AND I SAID WHY DID YOU COME
AND HE SAID WE HAD TO FEEL SOME
SORT OF CONNECTION AND TO
EXPRESS THE FEELINGS WE HAVE FOR
THE CHILDREN AND FOR THE
TEACHERS WHO IS SUFFERED SO
GREATLY AT SANDY HOOK.
WE WILL WATCH THIS THROUGHOUT
THE DAY AS IT GROWS INTO THE
EVENING HOURS AND THIS IS A
LOCAL NEWSPAPER HERE, THERE ARE
ONLY 27 NAMES, NOT 28, BUT NANCY
LANZA AGE 52, THE MOTHER OF THE
KILLER.
DOWN THE STREET FROM DANBURY,
CONNECTICUT, TEACH THEM WELL, A
QUOTE FROM THE PRESIDENT AT THE
VIGIL AND THE MEMORIAL CEREMONY.
COMMENTATORS ARE SPEAKING OF THE
SHOOTINGS HERE IN NEWTOWN.
WE WILL HAVE MORE COVERAGE AS
OUR TEAM CONTINUES LIVE IN
NEWTOWN.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] CAMPBELL'S
GREEN BEAN CASSEROLE.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO
>> THE SCHOOL SHOOTING HERE IN
NEWTOWN BRINGS THE ISSUE OF GUN
VIOLENCE TO THE FRONT BURNER.
THIS IS A COMPLICATED ISSUE AND
THE PRESS SECRETARY SAID THE
PRESIDENT SUPPORTS CERTAIN GUN
RESTRICTIONS HE SAID WE MUST
ALSO REASSESS HOW WE DOLE WITH
THINGS SUCH AS MENTAL HEALTH.
>> THE PRESIDENT HAS LONG
SUPPORTED REINSTATING THE
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN THAT EXPIRED
IN 2004.
AS THE PRESIDENT HAS SAID, AND I
JUST SAID THIS IS A COMPLEX
PROBLEM THAT REQUIRES COMPLEX
AND A VARIETY OF SOLUTIONS.
>>Reporter: A NEW ABC ABC --
ABC NEWS AND "WASHINGTON POST"
PEOPLE ARE AT 54 PERCENT WHO
WANT MORE STRICT GUN CONTROL
LAWS COMPARED TO 43 PERCENT WHO
OPPOSE THIS.
>> LAST NIGHT THE PRESIDENT GOT
HIGH MARKS ACROSS THE SPECTRUM
FOR FOCUSING LARGELY ON TRYING
TO BRING THE COUNTRY TOGETHER
BUT THE MIDDLE PART OF THE
SPEECH WHICH TALKED ABOUT
BROADLY SPEAKING TAKING SOME
SORT OF DRAMATIC ACTION, THE
REPORTERS ARE TRYING TO PUT MORE
MEAT ON THE BONES AND PRESS HOW
QUICKLY THE PRESIDENT WILL MOVE.
WHAT SPECIFICALLY WILL THE
PRESIDENT SUPPORT?
JAKE CARNEY WAS VAGUE.
>> AS YOU KNOW THE PRESIDENT HAS
TAKEN POSITIONS ON COMMON SENSE
MEASURES THAT HE BELIEVES SHOULD
BE TAKEN TO ADDRESS THIS PROBLEM
BUT HE MADE CLEAR THAT MORE
NEEDS TO BE DONE AND WE AS A
NATION HAVE NOT DONE ENOUGH TO
FULFILL OUR NUMBER ONE
OBLIGATION WHICH IS TO PROTECT
OUR CHILDREN.
>>Reporter: YOU CAN HEAR THE
QUESTIONS ABOUT GUN CONTROL BUT
HE STRUGGLED WITH EXPLAINING
WHAT, SPECIFICALLY, THE
PRESIDENT MIGHT DO OTHER THAN
THE ONE POINT YOU PLAYED EARLIER
ABOUT SUPPORTING THE BAN ON
ASSAULT WEAPONS, SENATOR
FEINSTEIN OF CALIFORNIA SAID SHE
IS ABOUT TO REINTRODUCE THAT AT
GOING OF JANUARY.
>> YOU CAN DEBATE GUN VIOLENCE
OR MANY THINGS ON THIS, I
MENTIONED MENTAL HEALTH, AND
VIOLENT MOVIES, VIDEO GAMES,
PRESCRIPTION MEDICATION, THE
RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN A PARENT
AND A SON BUT THERE APPEARS TO
BE PRESSURE FROM SOME REPUBLICAN
MEMBERS OF THE PARTY.
WHAT IS HAPPENING ON THAT?
>>Reporter: SOME REPUBLICANS
SAY, LOOK, DON'T RUSH INTO
ANYTHING, WE HAVE TO PROTECT THE
2nd AMENDMENT AND SOME
CONSERVATIVE DEMOCRATS THAT LIKE
TO PROTECT THE RIGHTS IN TERMS
OF HUNTING AND RECREATIONAL AND
SENATOR FROM WEST VIRGINIA SAID
HE WAS HUNDRED THIS WEEKEND, BUT
HE SAID NOW HE BELIEVES IT IS
TIME FOR THE PRESIDENT AND THE
CONGRESS TO COME TOGETHER ON
SOME, WHAT HE CALLED COMMON
SENSE MEASURES.
BOTTOM LINE, THOUGH, FROM WHAT
YOU HEARD THEY ARE NOT SURE
WHICH WAY THEY WILL GO SO MIKE
BLOOMBURG OF NEW YORK CITY SAID
IT IS TIME FOR FOLKS IN
WASHINGTON TO COME TOGETHER.
>> THE CONGRESS AND THE
PRESIDENT CANNOT FOCUS ON TWO
THINGS AT ONCE, WHO DID WE
ELECT?
>> HE WAS TALKING ABOUT THE
POSSIBILITY OF THE FISCAL CLIFF,
HE COLLINSING ACTION ON GUN
CONTROL.
CLEARLY THE MAYOR WOULD HAS BEEN
PRESSING THE PRESIDENT AND
OTHERS ON THIS ISSUE, HE
BELIEVES THEY SHOULD BE DOING
MULTIPLE THINGS AT ONCE.
>> THANK YOU, ED, FROM THE WHITE
HOUSE.
>>Reporter: SCHOOLS ARE TAKING
STEPS TO KEEP CHILDREN SAFE IN
THE AFTERMATH OF WHAT HAPPENED
HERE.
AN EXAMPLE IS THE DAY BEGAN IN A
NEW JERSEY SCHOOL WITH AN
ANNOUNCEMENT TO NOT ALLOW ANY
STRANGERS INSIDE THE BUILDING.
THAT IS COMING UP AS OUR COURAGE
CONTINUES LIVE IN SANDY HOOK,
CONNECTICUT.
Hmm, it says here that Cheerios
helps lower cholesterol
as part
of a heart healthy diet.
That's true.
...But you still have to go
to the gym.
♪ The one and only, Cheerios
PLAYS A KEY ROLE
THROUGHOUT OUR LIVES.
One A Day Men's 50+
IS A COMPLETE MULTIVITAMIN
DESIGNED FOR MEN'S HEALTH
CONCERNS AS WE AGE.
IT HAS 7 ANTIOXIDANTS
TO SUPPORT CELL HEALTH.
One A Day Men's 50+.
>> THE NEWTOWN MASSACRE WAS NOT
OUR FIRST SCHOOL SHOOTING AND OR
THE WORSE AND IT WILL LIKELY NOT
BE THE LAST.
THE QUESTION IS, WHAT CAN WE DO
BETTER TO PROTECT OUR CHILDREN?
ON THIS, THE FIRST MONDAY SINCE
THE SHOOTING, TEACHERS AND
ADMINISTRATORS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY NOW REVIEWING THEIR OWN
EMERGENCY PROTOCOLS.
MANY SCHOOLS ARE UPPING SECURITY
FOR SAFETY AND ALSO TO HELP EASE
THE ANXIETY OF MILLIONS OF
PARENTS WHO HAD A TOUGH TIME
THIS MORNING AND A LONG
CONVERSATION OVER THE WEEKEND
SAYING GOODBYE TO THEIR OWN
CHILDREN AS THEY JUMPED ON THE
SCHOOL BUS OR, IN FACT, REMAIN
DRIVEN TO THE SCHOOL BY THEIR
OWN PARENTS.
JAMES HAS MORE ON THAT STORY
WITH ME NOW.
JAMES?
>> PUBLIC AND PRIVATE SCHOOLS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY, AUTHORITIES
ARE BRACING FOR THE KIND OF
DIFFICULT QUESTIONS THAT
CHILDREN UNIQUELY TEND TO POSE.
>> IT IS VERY IMPORTANT THAT WE
HAVE SOME AGE-APPROPRIATE
DISCUSSIONS AS THE STUDENTS
BRING THEIR CONCERNS FORWARD SO
THAT WE CAN RETURN TO A SENSE OF
NORMAL OPERATIONS AS QUICKLY AS
WE CAN UNDER THE CIRCUMSTANCES.
>> SCHOOL SECURITY OFFICERS ARE
TOUCHING BASE WITH LOCAL POLICE.
PROCEDURES FOR SAFETY DRILLS ARE
BEING REVISITED.
PARENTS ARE BEING TOLD, WE
TRAINED IF THIS KIND OF
SITUATION.
SOME SCHOOLS OBSERVED A MOMENT
SILENCE BUT MANY SCHOOL
PRINCIPLED ERR ON THE SIDE OF
CAUTION AND NOT RAISING THIS AS
A SUBJECT.
ONE PRINCIPAL IN BROWARD COUNTY
SAID SCHOOL STAFF MEMBERS WILL
BE AVAILABLE TO SPEAK TO
INDIVIDUAL STUDENTS IF ANYONE
NEEDS SOMEONE TO TALK TO.
WE WILL NOT BRING UP THE LATEST
TRAGEDY OR OUR CONVERSATIONS BUT
WE WILL BE THERE FOR OUR
STUDENTS TO LISTEN IF THEY HAVE
CONCERNED ABOUT SAFETY AT OUR
SCHOOL.
>> MY OWN SON'S PRINCIPAL, HERE
IN THE WASHINGTON, DC, AREA,
E-MAILED ME AND OTHER PARENTS
LAST NIGHT.
"OUR APPROACH WILL BE TO ADDRESS
IT AS IT COMES UP WITH STUDENTS,
SOME OF THE CHILDREN WILL HAVE
HEARD OR SEEN DETAILS OF THEY
HAVE VENT ON TV AND OTHERS MAY
HAVE BEEN SHIELDED FROM THE
MAJORITY OF THE INFORMATION.
I DO NOT WANT ADULT INITIATED
CONVERSATIONS TO IMPRESS MORE ON
THE CHILDREN THAN PARENTS
DESIRE."
ANOTHER PRINCIPAL IN WASHINGTON,
DC AREA URGED PARENTS TO LIMIT
EXPOSURE TO THE VIOLENT AND
DISTURBING IMAGES AVAILABLE ON
TELEVISION AND COMPUTER SCREENS.
>>Reporter: AND PARENTS WANT
TO BE THE FIRST TO TALK TO KIDS
ABOUT SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
UNFORTUNATELY, ON A FRIDAY,
JAMES, SOCIAL MEDIA WORKED
FASTER THAN PARENT COULD GET TO
THEIR OWN KIDS WHICH WAS ANOTHER
SOURCE OF IRRITATION FOR HAVING
THAT CONVERSATION.
>> ESPECIALLY FOR THE 4th AND
5th GRADE THEY MORE MEDIA
SATURATED THAN A KID IN
KINDERGARTEN OR 1st GRADE.
>> THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER, NANCY
LANZA AGE 52, KNEW HER SON HAD
DIFFICULT, FROM FRIENDS OF THE
FAMILY.
A SHORT TIME AGO WE GOT AN
INTERESTING NEW DETAIL FROM THE
MEDIATOR IN THE MOTHER'S DIVORCE
PROCEEDING.
WE HAVE DETAILS ON THAT AHEAD.
>> THIS IS "STUDIO B" LIVE FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
IN THE PAST 20 MINUTES WE HAVE
SEEN SOME OF THE GIANT MOVING
VANS MOVE BEHIND US TAKING SOME
OF THE FURNITURE AND DESK
MATERIAL OUT OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
WE WILL GET MORE ON THAT IN A
MOMENT BUT NOW THIS IS A NEWS
CONFERENCE WE ARE WAITING FOR,
FROM THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT.
WE HAVE NOT HEARD FROM HIM YET
TODAY BUT THAT WILL START FROM
THE STATE CAPITAL IN HARTFORD IN
A FEW MOMENTS.
WE WILL BRING IT LIVE.
INVESTIGATORS ARE LOOKING FOR
ANSWERS AND ARE RUNNING TO WHERE
THE DEADLY DAY BEGAN.
THAT WOULD BE THE SHOOTER'S OWN
HOME.
ADAM LANZA LIVED THERE WITH HIS
MOTHER IN A WELL TO DO
NEIGHBORHOOD TEN MILES FROM OUR
LOCATION NEAR SANDY HOOK.
POLICE SAY HE BEGAN THE DAY
FRIDAY MORNING BY SHOOTING HIS
MOTHER SEVERAL TIMES IN THE HEAD
WHILE SHOW WAS STILL IN BED.
IF THERE WERE PROBLEMS BREWING
AT HOME YOU WOULD NOT HAVE KNOWN
IT FROM TALKING TO HER.
SHE RARELY DISCUSSED HER
HOMELIFE BUT WAS CLEARLY DEVOTED
TO HER CHILDREN.
A SHORT TIME AGO WE GOT WORD
THAT NANCY LANZA DID NOT LIKE TO
LEAVE HER SON ALONE.
NOW, WHAT ARE YOU LEARN ABOUT
THIS RELATIONSHIP?
>> THIS INFORMATION IS REPORTED
FROM A MEDIATOR THAT HELPED
NANCY AND PETER THROUGH THEIR
2009 DIVORCE.
THEY ARE REPORTING SHE FELT SHE
DIDN'T WANT TO LEAVE THE SON
ALONE BUT THE DIVORCE WAS GOING
CALMLY AND THE TWO PEOPLE
INVOLVED HERE AGREED ON HOW
THEIR SON SHOULD BE TREATED.
THINGS WENT RATHER QUICKLY AND
SHE DID NOT GET A LOT OF
INFORMATION OR A LOT OF TALK
GOING ON ABOUT THE SON.
>>Reporter: WHAT ARE FRIENDS
SAYING ABOUT THE CHALLENGES
THAT, PERHAPS, SHE FACED AS A
MOTHER TRYING TO RAISE HER
20-YEAR-OLD SON?
>> A DIFFICULT SITUATION.
SHE DID SPEAK OPENLY ABOUT HER
SON TO HER FRIENDS AND THEY ARE
DOWN THE STREET AT A LOCAL PUB
AND THEY ARE TELLING SIMILAR
STORIES THAT HER SON WAS
STRUGGLING, AND SHE DID ENJOY
HER HOBBY, USING GUNS BUT IT
WASN'T A KEY PART OF HER LIFE.
IN OTHER WORDS USING THE GUNS
WASN'T SOMETHING SHE TALKED
ABOUT BUT THEY DO BELIEVE SHE
DID TAKE HER SON SHOOTING.
AND ANOTHER SAID IT WAS PERHAPS
A HOBBY BUT NOT AS IT IS
SOMETIMES BEING MADE OUT IN THE
PRESS.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> SHE HAS BEEN DESCRIBED, I
THINK, AS SOME KIND OF GUN
ENTHUSIAST OR SURVIVALIST AND
THAT IS NOT THE NANCY I KNOW.
I KNOW SHE HAS GUNS AND SHE
ENJOYS TARGET SHOOTING AND
THAT'S ALL I KNOW.
IT IS NOT HER PRIMARY HOBBY.
>>Reporter: DESPITE THE FACT
THEY HAD SEVERAL TYPES OF
WEAPONS IN HER HOME.
>>Reporter: THERE IS MUCH MORE
TO LEARN.
WE WILL IN TIME.
THANK YOU, MOLLY.
ACCORDING TO ASSOCIATED PRESS
THIS HAS BREAKING NEWS WITH THE
GUN MAN'S RELATIONSHIP TO THE
GUNS IN THE HOME.
WE ARE TOLD A SPOKE MAN FROM
A.T.F. SAID THERE WERE GUNS
FIRED AT A SHOOTING RANGE OVER
THE PAST SEVERAL YEARS BUT THERE
IS NO EVIDENCE THAT ADAM LANZA
DID SO RECENTLY AND THERE IS NO
EVIDENCE HE SOMEHOW PRACTICED
FOR THE RAMPAGE.
READING FROM THE A.P.
INVESTIGATORS HAVE NO INDICATE
THAT THE "SHOOTINGER GAUGED IN
SHOOTING ACTIVISTS IN THE PAST
SIX MONTHS."
SO WE ARE JUST LOOKING AT THIS.
THAT IS A PICTURE FROM YEARS AGO
AS A MUCH YOUNGER MAN, AND THE
BLACK AND WHITE PHOTO IS MORE
RECENT.
THERE ARE TWO FUNERALS THAT HAVE
TAKEN PLACE ALREADY TODAY AND
THIS WILL BE THE FIRST A VERY
LONG AND SAD WAVE OF FUNERALS.
A STATE SENATOR HAS MET WITH
GRIEVING FAMILIES AFTER THE
VIOLENCE ON FRIDAY, ATTENDING
THE VIGIL WITH THE PRESIDENT,
AND HE WAS AT THE FUNERAL TODAY
OF A CHILD VICTIM AND SAYS THAT
AS A PARENT IT IS TOUGH FOR HIM
TO COMPREHEND THE LOSS OF 20 OF
NEWTOWN'S YOUNGSTERS.
THE SENATOR INTEREST ME NOW, AND
I WISH THE CIRCUMSTANCES WERE
DIFFERENT.
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
HOW ARE THE PEOPLE YOU CAME
ACROSS TODAY AT FUNERALS DOING
THIS AFTERNOON?
>> WELL, THANK YOU, I AM DOING
LIKE EVERYONE ELSE, NOT JUST IN
NEWTOWN BUT ACROSS OUR STATE AND
OUR NATION, I AM STILL IN A
STATE OF SHOCK AND SADNESS AND
IT IS STILL IMPOSSIBLE TO
COMPREHEND THAT SOMEONE COULD DO
THIS.
THE PEOPLE IN NEWTOWN ARE
FEELING THE SAME WAY: GRIEF.
SHOCK.
LAST NIGHT'S VIGIL WITH ALL THE
STATES AND TOWNS COMING TOGETHER
AND HAVING THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES THERE TO SPEAK
FROM HIS HEART AND I SAW A MAN
SPEAK AS A FATHER AS MUCH AS A
PRESIDENT, AND THAT WAS A VERY
IMPORTANT PART OF THE HEALING
PROCESS.
THIS WEEK WILL PROBABLY BE AS
TOUGH AS ANY, DEALING WITH
PUTTING TO REST THOSE 20 YOUNG
CHILDREN BUT IT IS PART OF THE
GRIEVING PROCESS.
>> HOW MANY MORE FUNERALS DO YOU
PLAN ON ATTENDING?
>> WELL, I AM GOING TO TRY TO
GIVE TO AT MANY AS I CAN AND PAY
MY RESPECTS AND LEND MY PRAYERS
TO THE FAMILY WHO SUFFERED SO
MUCH.
I HAVE GOTTEN SO MANY CALLS FROM
PEOPLE ALL OVER THE PLACE
OFFERING TO HELP WHICH IS SO, WE
ARE SO THANKFUL FOR THAT AND I
ASKED THEM TO CONTINUE TO BRING
IN WHATEVER THEY WANT TO, FOR
THE FAMILIES, FOR THE PEOPLE IN
TOWN, FOR THE REST OF THE
CHILDREN AND TEACHERS AND
ADMINISTRATORS WHO WERE IN THE
SCHOOL THAT DAY.
THEY HAVE A LONG ROAD AHEAD OF
THEM, AS WELL.
>> I WANT YOU TO KNOW HOW MANY
PEOPLE I HAVE MET TODAY THAT
HAVE DRIVEN HERE FROM ALL OVER
YOUR STATE OF CONNECTICUT, AND
MASSACHUSETTS, AND THE STATE OF
NEW YORK, AND THEY WANT TO BE
HERE TO EXPRESS WHATEVER THEY
CAN TO YOUR COMMUNITY AND TO THE
PEOPLE WHO HAVE LOST SO MUCH.
MY BEST TO YOU.
>>Guest: THANK YOU, SIR.
>>Reporter: AND A WARNING OF
COPYCAT ATTACKS AFTER SOMETHING
LIKE THIS.
POLICE HAVE APPREHENDED A PLAN
FOR POETING ONLINE THREATS
AGAINST ELEMENTARY
SCHOOLCHILDREN IN LOS ANGELES.
WHAT IS MORE, THEY SAY THEY
FOUND NOT ONE BUT NINE FIRE
AWAYS AT THE HOME WHERE THEY
ARRESTED THIS MAN.
TRACE HAS MORE ON THAT, LIVE
FROM THE WEST COAST NEWSROOM.
DO WE KNOW IF THE SUSPECT
THREATENED A SPECIFIC SCHOOL?
>> HE DIDN'T MENTION ANY NAMES
BUT POLICE SAY IN HIS FACEBOOK
THREAT HE DID SAY THERE WOULD BE
MULTIPLE SCHOOLS INVOLVED AND HE
DID REFER TO CONNECTICUT, THE
SHOOTING THIS, AND SAID THIS
WOULD BE "A LARGER SCALE."
POLICE HAVE NOW IDENTIFIED THE
SUSPECT AS A 24-YEAR-OLD WHO IS
A COLLEGE STUDENT AT CAL POLY
AND ARRESTED IN EAST HOLLYWOOD
AND HIS FATHER ALLOWED POLICE TO
SEARCH THE HOME AND THEY FOUND
THE NINE GUNS.
WE ARE TALKING TWO RIFLES, A
SHOTGUN, AND SIX HANDGUNS AND
LOADS OF AMMUNITION.
POLICE WERE ASKED ABOUT HOW
SERIOUS THEY BELIEVED THE LET
IS.
>> WE CERTAINLY TAKE ALL THREATS
LIKE THAT SERIOUSLY.
HE IS IN JAIL ON HALF A MILLION
BAIL.
WE TAKE IT SERIOUSLY BUT
ESPECIALLY IN LIGHT OF WHAT
HAPPENED IN CONNECTICUT WE WILL
DO EVERYTHING WE CAN TO KEEP
LOSSANCE SAFE.
>>Trace: THIS WERE NO
SUSPECTED BAD BEHAVIOR IN HIS
CRIMINAL HISTORY AT ALL AND WE
SHOULD NOTE, THEY DID NOT FIND
ANY WEAPON INSIDE HIS HOME JUST
AT HIS PARENT'S HOME.
>> THIS SCHOOL DISTRICT HAS TO
RESPOND.
WHAT ARE THEY SAYING?
>>Trace: IT HELPS HERE IF LOS
ANGELES THAT MOST OF THE SCHOOLS
IN LOS ANGELES COUNTY ARE ON
HOLIDAY BREAK.
THE SCHOOLS THAT ARE NOT ON
BREAK AND THAT ARE IN SESSION
ARE GETTING STEPPED UP POLICE
PATROLS.
THE HIGH SCHOOLS SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA ALREADY HAVE POLICE
OFFICERS ON CAMPUS AND NEW THIS
IS TALK OF EXPANDING THAT TO
MIDDLE SCHOOLS, EVEN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOLS.
>> WE FOCUSED HERE IN LOS
ANGELES AT PROVIDING OUR PARENTS
AND OUR GUARDIANS WITH ABSOLUTE
SENSE OF ASSURETY OF SAFETY SO
WE HAVE SPECIFIC MEASURES IN
PLACE ON THE CAMPUSES.
>>Trace: NO WORD WHEN THE
SUSPECT APPEARS IN COURT.
HE IS BEING HELD ON $500,000
BAIL.
>> THANK YOU, TRACE GALLAGHER.
30 MILES AWAY FROM HERE WE
REPORTED EARLIER WHEN SCHOOLS
WENT TO LOCKDOWN FOR AN HOUR,
THIS IS HOW ON EDGE YOU FIND
PEOPLE IN THE AREA, THEY FOUND A
MAN WHO WAS SPOTTED IN THE AREA
DRESSED IN BLACK WEARING A MASK
AND THEY THOUGHT HE WAS CARRYING
A RIFLE BUT IT WAS AN UMBRELLA.
THE SCHOOLS WENT IN LOOK DOWN
FOR AN HOUR AND THEY HAVE SINCE
RE-OPENED SELL HOURS AGO AND
THAT MAN HAS BEEN ARRESTED.
THE NET FROM POLICE HERE FOR
ANYONE MAKING ANY THREATS ONLINE
OR BY TELEPHONE IS SEVERE.
THAT IS AHEAD.
BUT FIRST, HOW SPEAKER BOEHNER
WENT BACK TO THE WHITE HOUSE
WITH THE LATEST OFFER TO KEEP
THE COUNTRY FROM GOING OVER THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
THAT IS AHEAD.
AND EGYPTIANS HAVE WRAPPED UP
THE FIRST ROUND OF VOTING ON A
CONTROVERSIAL NEW CONSTITUTION.
NOT EVERYONE IS PLEASED WITH THE
RESULTS.
THEY COULD BE IN FOR MORE
VIOLENT PROTESTS.
WE AWAIT A NEWS CONFERENCE FROM
THE GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT WHO
WILL SPEAK IF THE FIRST TIME
TODAY AS THE FAMILIES START TO
SAY THEIR GOODBYES.
HI. I'M HENRY WINKLER.
AND I'M HERE TO TELL HOMEOWNERS
THAT ARE 62 AND OLDER
ABOUT A GREAT WAY
TO LIVE A BETTER RETIREMENT.
IT'S CALLED A REVERSE MORTGAGE.
[ Male Announcer ]
CALL RIGHT NOW
TO RECEIVE YOUR FREE
DVD AND BOOKLET
WITH NO
OBLIGATION.
IT ANSWERS QUESTIONS LIKE
HOW A REVERSE MORTGAGE WORKS,
HOW MUCH YOU QUALIFY FOR,
THE WAYS TO RECEIVE YOUR MONEY,
AND MORE.
PLUS, WHEN
YOU CALL NOW,
YOU'LL GET THIS MAGNIFIER
WITH L.E.D. LIGHT
ABSOLUTELY FREE.
WHEN YOU CALL THE EXPERTS
AT One Reverse Mortgage TODAY,
YOU'LL LEARN THE BENEFITS
OF A GOVERNMENT-INSURED
REVERSE MORTGAGE.
IT WILL ELIMINATE
YOUR MONTHLY MORTGAGE PAYMENTS
AND GIVE YOU TAX-FREE CASH
FROM THE EQUITY IN YOUR HOME.
AND HERE'S THE BEST PART --
YOU STILL OWN YOUR HOME.
TAKE CONTROL
OF YOUR RETIREMENT TODAY.
♪
>> WE ARE KEEPING AN EYE ON
OTHER STORIES INCLUDING WORD
THAT REPUBLICANS HAVE PAID A NEW
OFFER TO KEEP US FROM GOING OVER
THE FISCAL CLIFF.
THE AUTOMATIC TAX HIKES AND
SPENDING CUTS ARE STILL SET TO
KICK IN LESS THAN TWO WEEKS FROM
NOW UNLESS LAWMAKERS CAN AGREE
ON A DEAL.
THE WHITE HOUSE TODAY SAID THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA WAS MEETING WITH
THE TOP REPUBLICAN IN CONGRESS,
SPEAKER BOEHNER, TO TALK IT OUT.
HOW DID THEY DO?
MIKE IS LIVE ON THE HILL.
HOW DID THE MEETING GO?
>> WELL, TOUGH TO TELL BECAUSE
BOTH SIDES HAVE BEEN TIGHTLIPPED
COULD BE A GOOD SIGN.
WE KNOW IT WAS LATE MORNING AND
IT LASTED 45 MINUTES AND IT WAS
A FACE-TO-FACE MEETING WITH THE
PRESIDENT AND THE SPEAKER AND
TREASURY SECRETARY FOLLOWING UP
ON A CRITICAL FRIDAY PHONE CALL
WHERE THE SPEAKER BOEHNER
OFFERED ESSENTIALLY TO INCREASE
TAXES ON THOSE MAKING MORE THAN
$1 MILLION.
THAT HAS BEEN A HUGE ISSUE IN
THE NEGOTIATIONS.
THE PRESIDENT HAS BEEN ARGUING
FOR INCREASING TAXES ON THOSE
MAKING MORE THAN $250,000.
THE SPEAKER BOEHNER OFFERED NEW
REVENUE IN TERMS OF TAXING
MILLIONAIRES AT THE WHITE HOUSE
TODAY.
CARNEY SAID THIS IS WHAT IS
NECESSARY FOR BROAD DEFICIT
REDUCTION.
>> A CERTAIN LEVEL OF REVENUE
GLEANED FROM THE WEALTHY HAS TO
BE MET AND THE ONLY WAY TO DO
THAT WAS THROUGH, IN PART,
RAISING REVENUE.
>> HARRY REID WANTED SENATORS TO
BE FRIENDED TO COME BACK TO WORK
ON THE FISCAL CLIFF THE DAY
AFTER CHRISTMAS.
>> ENJOY THAT.
WE ARE LEARNING OF A ROUGH
OUTLINE OF A POSSIBLE DEAL.
WHAT ARE THE DETAILS ON THAT?
DO YOU KNOW?
>> THAT WOULD INCLUDE $1
TRILLION IN SPENDING CUTS.
$1 TRILLION IN INCREASING
REVENUE.
THAT INCLUDES AN IMMEDIATE
DOWNPAYMENT AND LAWMAKERS
WORKING THE REST OUT NEXT YEAR.
POSSIBLY INCLUDED IS RAISING THE
DEBT LIMIT WHICH HAS BEEN
CRITICAL TO THE WHITE HOUSE,
EXTENDING UNEMPLOYMENT
INSURANCE, THE MEDICARE FIX AND
TAX EXTENDERS AND NOW AIDES TO
SPEAKER BOEHNER SAID IF HE IS
GOING TO AGREE TO INCREASE THE
DEBT LIMIT ESSENTIALLY THERE HAS
TO BE EQUAL CUTS OR REFORMS TO
ENTITLEMENTS TO MATCH.
SO HE WILL NOT JUST
AUTOMATICALLY INCREASE THE
CREDIT CARD ON THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT BUT SAYS THIS HAS TO
BE EQUAL CUTS TO ENTITLEMENTS.
>> YOU WONDER HOW MANY VOTES HE
CAN GET THERE IN THE HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES ON THAT.
WE WILL SOON FIND OUT.
THANK YOU, MIKE EMANUEL.
THAT IS A BIG STORY IN
WASHINGTON, DC.
THE OTHER STORY FROM THE MIDDLE
EAST GOES TO THE HEART OF EGYPT.
THEY ARE BRACING FOR MASSIVE
NATION-WIDE PROTESTS TOMORROW
AGAINST THE COUNTRY'S PRESIDENT
AS WELL AS THE NEWLY DRAFTED
CONSTITUTION.
THEY ARE VOTING, REMEMBER, AND
DEMONSTRATORS HAVE RALLIED
AGAINST PRESIDENT MORSI RECENTLY
WHO TRIED TO GRANT HIMSELF
ABSOLUTE POWER.
THE PROTESTS GREW WHEN THE
ALLIES DRAFT ADD CONSTITUTION
THAT WOULD GIVE HARD-LINE
ISLAMISTS MORE SWAY IN THE
LARGELY SECULAR ISLAMIC COUNTRY.
REMEMBER, EGYPT OFTEN MEDIATES
FEUDS AND PEACE TREATIES BETWEEN
ISRAEL AND THE ENEMY AND THEY
ARE CRITICAL TO MIDDLE EAST
PEACE.
OVER THE WEEKEND THE
CONSTITUTION PASSED A
PRELIMINARY VOTE, 57 PERCENT OF
THE BALLOT, AND THAT IS SAID TO
BE QUITE A BIT LESS THAN THE
PRESIDENT EXPECTED BUT THE VOTE
WAS RIDDLED WITH IRREGULARITIES.
BACK YOU NEGOTIATION YOU IN NOW
TOWN WHERE THE GOVERNOR MALLOY
IS HOLDING A NEWS CONFERENCE IN
HARTFORD.
WE EXPECTED THIS TO BEGIN A
SHORT TIME AGO AND HE NOW IS
TALKING.
WE WILL DROP IN AND HEAR WHAT HE
HAS TO SAY.
HERE THE GOVERNOR.
>> YOU THINK IT WILL NEVER
HAPPEN IN YOUR HOME BUT CLEARLY
IT DID IN CONNECTICUT.
I WILL REPEAT SOMETHING I SAID
ON FRIDAY AND SATURDAY.
THE FAMILIES OF THOSE VICTIMS,
THEIR FAMILIES, THEIR RELATIVES,
THE TEACHERS AND ADMINISTRATORS
AT THE SCHOOL WHO SURVIVED AND
THE CHILDREN WHO SURVIVED I SAY
ON BEHALF OF THE STATE WE STAND
READY TO ASSIST YOU IN ANY WAY
POSSIBLE, IN ANY WAY NEEDED TO
HELP YOU HEAL.
SO MANY RESOURCES ALREADY ARE
BEING BROUGHT TO BEAR BUT WE
WILL BRING MORE, WHATEVER IS
NECESSARY, AND DO WHATEVER HAS
TO BE DONE, TO HELP OUR STATE
AND THE COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN
AND, ALSO, THE SPECIFIC
NEIGHBORHOOD OF HANDY HOOK.
TO THAT END, FOR ALL OF OUR
CITIZENS, MUTT JUST FOR A
GEOGRAPHIC BASIS, ANYONE WHO IS
HURTING IN THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT, CALL 211, THE
CRISIS LINE AVAILABLE ON A
STATE-WIDE BASIS, AVAILABLES 24
HOUR AS DAY TO CONNECT FAMILIES
WITH THE RESOURCES THEY NEED TO
GET THROUGH THE CIRCUMSTANCES.
IT IS STAFFED BY PEOPLE WHO ARE
TRAINED, TRAINED SPECIALISTS IN
HANDLING THESE KINDS OF
SITUATIONS.
WE HAVE USED THE UNITED WAY AND
211 TO HELP COORDINATE THE MANY
OFFERS OF SERVICES THAT ARE
COMING INTO OUR STATE.
WE WILL USE MANY OF THOSE
RESOURCES, I AM SURE.
>> I WANT TO AGAIN THANK THE
PRESIDENT IF HAVING COME TO THE
STATE AND HAVING PLEDGED TO
PROVIDE ON BEHALF OF THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT THE PRESENCE THAT WE
NEEDED IN NEWTOWN AND ANY
ADDITIONAL SERVICES THAT WE
MIGHT NEED.
I COMMENT THAT HE WAS ELOQUENT
AND MOVING AND HEALING AND HE
WAS POWERFUL.
I CAN SPEAK ON BEHALF OF
EVERYONE WHEN I SAY, WE ARE
GRATEFUL FOR HIS LEADERSHIP AND
IT IS OBVIOUS HE IS CONCERNED
ABOUT OUR STATE AND OUR PEOPLE
AND I AM MOST APPRECIATIVE OF
THAT.
I THANK THE FIRST RESPONDERS.
IT IS PRETTY CLEAR, NOW, THEIR
VERY QUICK RESPONSE SAVED LIKES.
WE ARE GRATEFUL TO THEM THEY PUT
THEIR LIVES ON THE LINE EVERY
SINGLE DAY AND THERE ARE DAYS
LIKE FRIDAY WHEN THEY PUT THEIR
LIVES ON THE LINE AND THEY
ACTUALLY SAVE LIVES AS THEY
CLEARLY DID ON FRIDAY.
AS A RESULT, CHILDREN WENT HOME
AND CONTINUED THE PREPARATIONS
TO CELEBRATE CHRISTMAS OR WILL
CELEBRATE HANUKAH IN THE FUTURE.
>> I WOULD LIKE TO THANK THE
ADULTS IN THE SCHOOL, THE
TEACHERS AND THE ADMINISTRATORS,
THOSE WHO DIES TRYING TO SAVE
THEIR STUDENTS ARE HEROES.
THEY GAVE THEIR LIVES SO OTHERS
COULD LIVE.
THIS ARE THOSE, TEACHERS WHO IN
QUICK THINKING ACTION SAVED MANY
LIVES.
THEY ARE HEROES, ALSO.
THERE ARE AT ARE A LOT OF HEROSN
CONNECTICUT TODAY.
I SAID ON SATURDAY NIGHT I
THOUGHT THERE WOULD BE A TIME
FOR PUBLIC DISCUSSION AND THAT
DISCUSSION WOULD INEST BRING
OCCUR AS IT DOES WHEN A TRAGEDY
LIKE THIS TAKES PLACE.
SOME PEOPLE INTERPRETED THAT TO
MEAN THAT I THOUGHT IT WAS
INAPPROPRIATE FOR THOSE
DISCUSSIONS TO TAKE PLACE.
I DO NOT THINK IT SIN
APPROPRIATE FOR THEM TO SAKE
PLACE.
IN FACT, IT IS QUITE
APPROPRIATE.
I WAS MAKING THE POINT NO MORE
THAN 36 HOURS AFTER THE EVENT MY
PERSONAL JOB AS GOVERNOR AT
THAT MOMENT, WAS TO SPEAK TO THE
PEOPLE OF CONNECTICUT ABOUT THE
FEARS THEY FEEL, THE DAMAGE THAT
HAS BEEN DONE, AND MY JOB WAS TO
HELP AND CONTINUE TO HELP
NEWTOWN AND THE ENTIRE STATE TO
RECOVER.
WE KNOW IN OUR STATE THAT WE
HAVE SOME OF THE TOUGHEST GUN
LAWS OF ANY STATE IN THE NATION
BUT WHEN THE INVESTIGATION IS
OVER AND ALL OF THE INFORMATION
IS IN I WILL ASK A FEW
QUESTIONS.
IS THERE A LAW, A POLICY OR
PROCEDURE WE COULD HAVE HAD ON
THE BOOK THAT MIGHT HAVE
PREVENTED THIS VAT JOY?
IT TURNS OUT CLEARLY THE ANSWER
IS YES AND I BELIEVE IT IS YES,
AND WE SHOULD PURSUE THAT
STRATEGY.
ARE WE DOING ENOUGH FROM MY
MENTAL IT PERSPECTIVE TO REACH
OUT TO KIDS AND FAMILIES WHO ARE
OBVIOUSLY IN TROUBLE?
MY SENSE IS WE ARE NOT.
WE NEED TO LOOK AT THAT IN OUR
OWN STATE AND OUR OWN NATION.
>>Reporter: THAT IS THE
GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT WHO IS
GOING THROUGH WHAT HE HAS BEEN
DOING TODAY.
WHAT WE LEARNED EARLIER TODAY
THIS ARE MANY, MANY WITNESSES
THAT STILL HAVE TO BE
QUESTIONED.
SOME OF THE WITNESSES ARE THE
YOUNG CHILDREN WHO SURVIVED
INSIDE THE SCHOOL, THE
CONNECTICUT POLICE TOLD ME EARLY
TODAY THAT THIS IS ABSOLUTELY
ESSENTIAL TO TALK TO THE YOUNG
BOYS AND GIRLS, TO PAINT A
PICTURE AND GET A FULL IDEA OF
WHAT HAPPENED.
THE SCHOOL BEHIND ME IS A CRIME
SCENE UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE AND
IT IS NOT DEALER WHEN THE SCHOOL
WILL OPEN UP AGAIN OR EVEN IF IT
WILL.
YOU HER THE GOVERNOR SAY THAT
FIRST RESPONDERS SAVED LIKES.
WE TOLD THROUGH LOCAL POLICE
THAT THE SIRENS THAT THE GUNMAN
HEARD WHILE HE WAS NEED THE
SCHOOL FORCED HIM TO PULL THE
TRIGGER ON HIMSELF EARLIER THAN
HE EXPECTED LEAVING HUNDREDS OF
ROUNDS OF AMMUNITION UNUSED IN
THAT SCHOOL BUILDING.
WE TALKED ABOUT A LOT OF THINGS
THE LAST FEW DAYS AND ONE IS
MENTAL HEALTH AND THE SHE BACK
IN THE SPOT LIGHT NOT JUST THOSE
OF SHOOTER BUT THOSE FACING THE
SURVIVORS AND VICTIMS' FAMILY
THIS IS NO DOUBT THAT THOSE WHO
FRIENDS AND LOVERED ONES DIED
HAVE A LONG ROAD AHEAD.
IT IS CRITICAL TO HELP THEM TO
PREVENT MORE SERIOUS EMOTIONAL
ISSUES IN THE FUTURE.
WE ME ARE FAMILY AND YOUTH
TRAUMA EXPERT, AND CHILD FAMILY
AND NEUROPSYCHIATRY, DOCTOR,
THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME.
ONE THING YOU TOLD OUR PRODUCERS
WHAT WE DON'T KNOW IS AS
IMPORTANT AS WHAT WE DO KNOW.
WHAT ARE YOU REFERRING TO ABOUT
WHAT WE DON'T KNOW?
>>Guest: IT IS REALLY
IMPORTANT WE DON'T LABEL THE
SHOOTER UNTIL WE KNOW A LOT MORE
OF THE FACTS.
WHAT HAPPENS IF WE LABEL TOO
USUALLY IS THERE ARE YOUNG
PEOPLE ALL OVER OUR COUNTRY AND
ELSEWHERE WATCHING THE NEWS AND
PANICKING THAT THEY ARE GOING TO
BE LABELED AS BEING ON THE
AUTISM SPECTRUM AND, THEREFORE,
BEING VIOLENT OR HAVING A MENTAL
ILLNESS AND, THEREFORE, BEING
VIOLENT.
WE HAVE TO BE EXTREMELY CAREFUL
ABOUT CREATING WIDE-SPREAD PANIC
AND, ALSO, EXPOSING YOUNG PEOPLE
TO POSSIBLE BLAME AND LABELING.
OUR FOCUS NEEDS, INSTEAD, TO BE
ON HEALING.
WE NEED TO PREVENT THIS FROM
HAPPENING AGAIN AND PREVENTING
THE LONG-TERM CONSEQUENCES OF
THE TRAUMA.
>> I CAN UNDERSTAND THAT, THE
OTHER POINT YOU MADE IS, HELP
THE SURVIVORS NOW.
IT SEEMS LIKE LOGIC.
WHY STRESS THAT POINT?
>> TRAUMA, LEFT TO ITS OWN
DEVICES, RESULTS IN MANY
HORRIBLE THINS LIKE ADDICTION,
DEPRESSION, SUICIDE,
POST-TRAUMATIC STRESS F WE WORK
WITH THE FAMILIES AND THE
COMMUNITY TO BAND TOGETHER WE
ARE GOING TO BE ABLE TO PREVENT
THOSE LONG TERM CONSEQUENCES
THAT DECIMATE THE COMMUNITY EVER
FURTHER.
>> DOCTOR, THANK YOU, FROM
CALIFORNIA.
ASPIRIN, REALLY?
I HAVEN'T THOUGHT ABOUT ASPIRIN
FOR YEARS.
ASPIRIN WOULDN'T REALLY HELP
MY HEADACHE, I DON'T THINK.
ASPIRIN IS JUST OLD SCHOOL.
PEOPLE HAVE DOUBTS
ABOUT TAKING ASPIRIN FOR PAIN.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
WHAT'S DIFFERENT?
IT HAS MICRO-PARTICLES.
ENTERS THE BLOODSTREAM FAST
ITO THE SITE OF PAIN.S.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
Progresso.
In what world do potatoes,
bacon and cheese
add up to 100 calories?
Your world.
♪
[ whispers ]
Real bacon...