DOESN'T HAVE TO INTERFERE
THEIR LIFE.
WILL IT INFLUENCE, YES.
BUT THE COMMUNITY CAN COME
TOGETHER AND HEAL ONE ANOTHER
IF IT LANDLES IT PROPER LOW
AND ITS LIKE THEY ARE MOVING
THAT WAY.
>> ONE PROBLEM 150,000
SCHOOLINGS.
>> I HAVE A LOT OF MEP.
AND TELL YOU WHAT.
YOU SEE THOSE KIDS COMING OUT
IN THE LINE.
ONE LITTLE GIRL WAS CRYING AND
THE GIRL ON THE SMILE ON THE
FACE THEY REACT DIFFERENTLY.
>> OUR THOUGHT PRAYERS ARE
THE FAMILY.N AND OBVIOUSLY
STAY TUNED WITH THE CONTINUOUS
COVERAGE.
GRETA IS NEXT.
>> THIS IS IT A FOX NEWS
ALERT.
NEW INFORMATION ABOUT
>> GRETA: NEW INFORMATION ABOUT
THE ABSOLUTE UNTHINKABLE.
20 MERE CHILDREN, SO SMALL, THEY
DID NOT COME UP TO OUR WAIST.
THE INDESCRIBABLE HORROR BEGAN,
WHEN UNSUSPECTING PARENTS
DROPPED THEIR CHILDREN OFF AT
SCHOOL.
AT THE TIME, NEITHER THE PARENTS
NOR THE CHILDREN COULD HAVE
ANTICIPATED WHAT WAS ABOUT TO
HAPPEN.
IT ALL STARTED ABOUT 9:00 A.M.
A KILLER WALKS INTO THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HERE IN
CONNECTICUT AND STARTS SHOOTING.
WE ARE LEARNING NEW INFORMATION
AND WE WILL HAVE IT THROUGHOUT
THE HOUR.
WE START WITH RICK LEV ANTHOL
WITH THE LATEST.
>> Reporter: WE KNOW HIS NAME.
ADAM LANZA, 20 YEARS OLD.
HE LIVED HERE WITH HIS MOTHER,
NANCY, WHO AUTHORITIES SAY WAS
SHOT DEAD IN HER BED THIS
MORNING IN THEIR HOME, THAT SHE
SHARED WITH THE SHOOTER.
HE THEN TOOK HER CAR AND AT
LEAST THREE WEAPONS, MAYBE MORE,
INCLUDING A GLOCK, A SIX HOUR
AND AN MF-TYPE ASSAULT RIFLE.
WENT TO THE SCHOOL WHERE HIS
MOTHER WORKED AS A SUBSTITUTE
TEACHER AND GOT THROUGH SECURITY
AND WENT TO TWO ROOMS IN ONE
AREA OF THE SCHOOL AND BEGAN
SHOOTING CHILDREN AND ADULTS.
HE SHOT 20 KIDS.
18 DIED AT THE SCENE.
TWO WERE TAKEN TO THE HOSPITAL
AND DIED.
HE SHOT SIX OTHER ADULT,
INCLUDING THE PRINCIPAL, BEFORE
ENDING HIS OWN LIFE BEFORE
POLICE ARRIVED AT THE SCHOOL.
>> GRETA: IS THERE ANY REPORT OF
WHAT HE WAS SAYING AND WHETHER
HE WAS DRESSED IN ANY UNUSUAL
WAY OR ANYTHING PECULIAR?
>> Reporter: WE HEARD FROM A
SIX-YEAR-OLD BOY IN A CLASSROOM
AND SAID THE SHOOTER CAME IN,
SHOT THE TEACHER AND THE BOY
GRABBED HIS CLASSMATESMATES ANDN
OUT.
HE SAID THE SHOOTER DIDN'T SAY A
SINGLE WORD.
WE HAVE HEARD FROM THE SHOOTER'S
BROTHER THAT SHE WAS LEARNING
DISABLED, MAY HAVE BEEN
AUTISTIC.
WE KNOW THAT THE BROTHER AND THE
FATHER ARE BREWED BY THE FBI.
>> GRETA: AND THE MOTHER,
SUBSTITUTE TEACHER, WAS SHE
SUPPOSED TO TEACH TODAY?
WAS THERE ANYTHING UNUSUAL ABOUT
HER BEING HOME?
>> Reporter: WE DON'T KNOW
THAT.
THE MAN WOKE UP AND SHOT HIS
MOTHER IN THE HOME, TOOK HER
CAR, TOOK HER GUNS AND WENT TO
THE SCHOOL WHERE SHE WORKED AND
BEGAN THIS RAMPAGE.
>> GRETA: THIS IS SO
UNTHINKABLE.
WE TALKED OFF CAMERA BEFOREHAND,
THE IDEA OF WALK INTERESTING A
CLASSROOM AND SHOOTING
CHILDREN -- LITTLE KIDS.
5- 6-YEAR-OLD KIDS.
IT MAKES NO SENSE.
>> GRETA: A PRINCIPAL AND OTHER
ADULTS?
>> Reporter: APPARENTLY, THERE
WERE MORNING ANNOUNCEMENTS GOING
ON.
SOME OF THE KIDS AND ADULTS
HEARD THE SCREAMS OVER THE P.A.
SYSTEM, IN ADDITION TO HEARING
THE GUNFIRE, RINGING THROUGH THE
HALLWAYS BECAUSE THE SHOTS WERE
FIRED IN AN AREA WHERE THE
MORNING ANNOUNCEMENTS WERE BEING
MADE.
>> GRETA: RICK, THANK YOU.
20 CHILDREN WERE MURDERED IN THE
SCHOOL WHERE THEY, OF COURSE,
SHOULD BE SAFE.
WE HAVE SOMEONE WHO TEACHES
BEFORE AND AFTER-SCHOOL PROGRAMS
AND HE IS HERE.
RAY, YOUR THOUGHTS TONIGHT?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
12, 13 HOURS AFTER THIS.
I AM SO NUMB NOW, I HAVE BEEN
CRYING AND EMOTIONAL FOR...
MOST OF THE DAY.
AND SPEAKING WITH WORK
ASSOCIATES WHO WORK WITH ME AT
THE SCHOOL, FAMILY AND FRIEND
WHO IS HAVE BEEN CALLING.
AT THIS POINT, I AM NUMB.
>> GRETA: RAY, YOU NEVER SAW
THIS SHOOTER BEFORE, DID YOU?
OR HEAR ANYTHING ABOUT HIM IN
THE COMMUNITY?
>> NO.
NO.
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
I LEFT THE SCHOOL, WE GENERALLY
WORK UNTIL 9:00, 9:30, 9:20 AND
THEN LEAVE.
THE STUDENTS COME IN TO GO TO
CLASS.
THAT'S WHEN WE TURN THEM OVER TO
THE REGULAR TEACHERS.
IT HAS TO BE 5 MINUTES, MAYBE
THAT -- FROM WHEN WE LEFT THAT
THIS OCCURRED.
>> GRETA: YOU KNOW, IT'S SO
UNTHINKABLE THAT THIS COULD
HAPPEN.
YOU KNOW, I CAN'T EVEN IMAGINE
WHAT YOUR COMMUNITY'S GOING
THROUGH TONIGHT.
EVEN -- I DON'T KNOW -- YOU
KNOW, WHERE DO YOU BEGIN TO, YOU
KNOW, PUT THE SCHOOL BACK
TOGETHER AND HEAL THESE
FAMILIES?
>> YOU KNOW, YOU TELL ME,
PLEASE.
IT'S JUST SO UNBELIEVABLE.
WE ARE ALL LOOKING AT EACH
OTHER.
I JUST CAME FROM THE...
THEY HAD A VIGIL AT THE LOCAL
CHURCH IN THE TOWN.
AND THERE WERE HUNDREDS AND
HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE THERE.
AND WE WERE JUST ALL -- WE
COULDN'T BELIEVE THAT WE ARE NOW
GOING THROUGH -- THE WONDERFUL
STATUS OF BEING THE SECOND WORST
DISASTER IN THE HISTORY OF THE
UNITED STATES.
>> GRETA: RAY, THANK YOU.
>> YOU'RE WELCOME.
>> GRETA: TONIGHT, MEMBERS OF
THIS GRIEF-STRICKEN COMMUNITY
GATHERING FOR A MEMORIAL SERVICE
MOLLY IS LIVE OUTSIDE THE
CHURCH, WHERE THE SERVICE WAS
HELD.
MOLLY?
>> Reporter: WE ARE ONE OF THE
CHURCHES HERE IN THIS COMMUNITY
THAT HELD VIGIL TONIGHT.
A NUMBER OF CHURCHES AND PLACES
AROUND TOWN ALLOWED PEOPLE TO
GATHER AND REFLECT ON WHAT
HAPPENED HERE.
THIS COMMUNITY, JUST BEGINNING
TO COME TO GRIPS WITH THE GRIEF
THAT WILL BE EXPERIENCE IN THE
COMING DAYS.
I HAD A CHANCE TO SPEAK WITH MY
SENIOR HERE, HE SPENT THE DAY
WITH SOME OF THE PARENT WHO IS
ACTUALLY LOST THEIR CHILDREN.
HE SAID THEY ARE HOLDING UP AS
WELL AS CAN POSSIBLY BE
EXPECTED, SHARING SOME OF THE
JOYFUL MEMORIES THEY HAD WITH
THEIR CHILDREN.
IN THIS TIME WHEN THE PEOPLE
JOY, THE BIRTH OFE PREPARING
CHRIST AND CELEBRATING CHRISTMAS
WITH TWINKLING LIGHTS, I ASKED
HIM, HOW DO PEOPLE COPE AT THIS
TIME, CHRISTMAS TIME.
HE SAID THERE ARE 20 BRIGHTER
STARS IN HEAVEN.
JUST ONE THOUGHT OF WHAT THIS
COMMUNITY HAS LOST, 20 CHILDREN
GONE, PEOPLE JUST BEGINNING TO
COPE, JUST BEGINNING TO COME
TOGETHER.
TODAY, I SPENT SOME TIME ON THE
MAIN STREET.
THIS IS A TINY THROW-BACK MAIN
STREET.
MOM-AND-POP SHOPS.
WE TALKED TO A WOMAN WHO CUTS
CHILDREN'S HAIR SPECIFICALLY, IN
TOWN.
SHE WAS WAITING TO HEAR HOW MANY
OF THE KIDS THAT SHE KNOWS WERE
AMONG THE INJURED OR AMONG THE
DEAD.
WE ALSO SPENT TIME IN THE
COMMUNITY IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD,
WHERE THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER
LIVED, WHERE SHE WAS MURDERED
THIS MORNING.
WHERE SHE WAS SHOT BEFORE HER
SON, ADAM, TOOK HER FAMILY CAR
AND HEADED FOR THE SCHOOL.
BEAUTIFUL, BIG HOMES -- AN
ADORABLE NEIGHBORHOOD.
ABSOLUTELY FILLED WITH CHRISTMAS
LIGHTS.
IT WOULD LOOK LIKE ANY OTHER
JOY-FILLED NEIGHBORHOOD IN THIS
TIME OF THE HOLIDAYS.
BUT INSTEAD, IT WAS MARKED OFF
WITH YELLOW CRIME TAPE.
WE COULD BARELY SEE AROUND THE
CORNER TO WHERE THE HOME WAS, TO
WHERE THE S.W.A.T. TEAMS AND THE
AUTHORITIES THAT HAD BEEN THERE
EARLIER IN THE DAY INVESTIGATING
HAD SPENT THEIR TIME, HAD SPENT
THEIR TIME EARLIER IN THE DAY.
WE WERE THERE AT 3:00 IN THE
AFTERNOON, WHEN THE S.W.A.T.
TEAM MEMBER, WHEN THE
INVESTIGATORS STARTED TO CLEAR
OUT AND WE COULD SEE THE
MANPOWER THAT THEY INVESTED IN
THAT NEIGHBORHOOD, EARLIER IN
THE DAY, WHEN THEY FINALLY FOUND
OUT WHERE TO GO TO BEGIN TO LOOK
FOR CLUES AS TO WHY HE WOULD
HAVE PARTICIPATED IN THIS,
PLANNED SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
HOW THIS COULD HAVE OCCURRED.
THEY WERE THERE TO LOOK FOR ANY
CLUES AND ANY CONTINUING IT
DANGER.
THAT'S BEING SECURED TONIGHT.
STILL HAVE PEOPLE THERE, KEEPING
AN EYE ON THINGS IN THAT
COMMUNITY.
BUT AS YOU MIGHT UNDERSTAND,
DEVASTATED NEIGHBORS, CONFUSED
NEIGHBORS IN THAT COMMUNITY,
CERTAINLY NOT USED TO SOMETHING
LIKE THIS, OCCURRING IN A
NEIGHBORHOOD LIKE NEWTOWN.
THIS IS A PLACE WHERE PEOPLE
MOVE INTENTIONALLY TO RAISE
THEIR CHILDREN, FOR THE SCHOOL
SYSTEM, FOR THE ADORABLE
THROW-BACK COMMUNITY, FOR THAT
ESSENCE OF WHAT EVERYONE WANTS
THEIR CHILDREN TO EXPERIENCE
THAT, TRUE SMALL-TOWN FEELING,
WHERE HUNDREDS AND HUNDREDS OF
PEOPLE WILL SHOW UP AT A
COMMUNITY CHURCH TO GRIEVE AND
JOIN TOGETHER AND TO WORK
TOWARDS REPAIR.
>> GRETA: THANK YOU.
THIS MASS MURDER INVESTIGATION
STRETCHING FROM CONNECTICUT TO
NEW JERSEY.
TONIGHT, WE LEARN THE KILLER'S
BROTHER HAS BEEN TAKEN IN FOR
QUESTIONING IN HOBOKEN, SORT OF
VOLUNTARILY -- NOT TAKEN INTO
CUSTODY.
THAT'S WHERE WE HAVE ANNA
COYMAN, STANDING BY LIVE.
WHAT YOU CAN TELL ME ABOUT THE
BROTHER AND THE QUESTIONING?
>> Reporter: WE ARE STANDING
IN FRONT OF HIS HOME,
24-YEAR-OLD RYAN, THE BROTHER OF
THE ALLEGED SHOOTER.
I CAN ACTUAL, LESS THAN AN HOUR
AGO, POLICE ROLLED UP THEIR
TAPE.
IT HAD BEEN BLOCKING THE
ENTRANCE OF THE BUILDING, WHICH
WAS SURROUNDED EARLIER THIS
AFTERNOON.
WE HEAR FROM A RELIABLE FEDERAL
SOURCE THAT WHEN POLICE WERE
SURROUNDING THE AREA, EARLIER
THIS AFTERNOON, RYAN AND HIS
GIRLFRIEND SHOWED UP.
THAT'S WHEN THEY REALIZED
EVERYTHING THAT WAS GOING ON.
HE WAS HANDCUFFED.
TAKEN AWAY.
WAS QUESTIONED.
WE ARE HEARING FROM THE FBI THAT
HE AND HIS FATHER BOTH HAVE BEEN
RELEASED.
THEY WERE VERY -- YOU KNOW,
COOPERATIVE, THROUGHOUT ALL OF
THIS.
BUT WE ARE ALSO HEARING FROM
RESIDENTS HERE WHO ARE JUST
REALLY RATTLED BY ALL OF THIS.
THEY SAY THE BOMB SQUAD WAS
RUNNING THROUGH THEIR HALLWAYS
TODAY, DAY CARE IN THE AREA WAS
ON LOCKDOWN.
AND PARENTS WERE GETTING EMAIL,
DON'T WORRY ABOUT YOUR KIDS, BUT
THIS IS WHAT IS GOING ON.
THEY HAVE BEEN ON EDGE.
THEY ARE REALLY HAPPY THAT
THINGS ARE CALMING DOWN AND
THANKFUL THAT THEIR KIDS ARE ALL
RIGHT.
>> GRETA: DO YOU KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT THE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN
THE FATHER -- AND THE SHOOTER OR
THE BROTHER AND THE SHOOTER OR
EVEN THE FATHER AND THE MOTHER
WHO HAS BEEN SHOT TODAY?
ANYTHING ABOUT THE FAMILY
DYNAMICS?
>> Reporter: WELL, WE HAVE
HEARD A LOT OF REPORT IT'S
NOTHING THAT WE HAVE CONFIRMED.
WE HAVE CALLS INTO THE FAMILIES.
BUT YOU CAN IMAGINE, YOU KNOW,
THEY -- THEY ARE SAYING THEY
NEED THEIR TIME AND NOT TAKING
OUR CALLS AT THE MOMENT.
BUT IT'S -- APPEARS THAT SOME OF
THE RELATIONSHIPS HAVE BEEN
SPOTTY.
ALSO, THE FATHER AND MOTHER ARE
DIVORCED.
THE FATHER HAS REMARRIED AND
LIVES IN CONNECTICUT.
WE ARE TOLD BY THE FBI, HE AND
THE SON RYAN, WHO DOES LIVE
HERE, MAY BE ON THEIR WAY TO
CONNECTICUT.
WE HAVE NOT SEEN RYAN HERE.
WE CAN TELL THAT YOU ALTHOUGH
RYAN IS NOT A SUSPECT,
AUTHORITIES ARE TELLING US THAT
THEY ARE GOING THROUGH HIS PHONE
RECORDS AND THROUGH HIS
COMPUTER, JUST TO SEE IF THAT
COULD GIVE THEM ANY POSSIBLE
CLUES ABOUT ANYTHING AND EVEN
POSSIBLY A MOTIVE.
>> GRETA: THANK YOU.
POLICE TELLING US, TELL TAKE
DAYS TO PROCESS THE GRUESOME
CRIME SCENE.
26 PEOPLE -- MERE CHILDREN --
SLAUGHTERED INSIDE THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE SPOKE WITH THE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE.
NICE TO SEE YOU, SIR.
>> THANK YOU.
>> GRETA: WE HAVE SEEN SO MANY
OF THOSE, IN COLUMBINE AND
BEFORE THAT.
YOU NEVER THINK IT'S GOING TO
HAPPEN IN YOUR COMMUNITY, DO
YOU?
>> NO, YOU DON'T.
THIS IS HORRIFIC.
IT'S TRAGIC, THE PARENTS SENT
THE CHILDREN TO SCHOOL TO BE
EDUCATED AND NEVER EXPECTED
NEVER TO SEE THEM AGAIN.
IT'S A HEART-BREAKING TRAGEDY
THAT THIS COMMUNITY IS ENDURING.
>> GRETA: YOU THINK RIGHT NOW,
YOU HAVEN'T IDENTIFIED ALL THE
BODIES, HAVE YOU?
>> WE HAVE NOT.
WE HAVE TENTATIVE
IDENTIFICATION.
WE HAVE TO POSITIVELY IDENTIFY
EVERYONE.
WE CERTAINLY WANT TO DO THAT AS
EXPEDITIOUSLY AS POSSIBLE.
WE ARE WORKING ON THAT AS WE
SPEAK.
WE WILL WORK THROUGH THE NIGHT.
IT'S IMPORTANT FOR THE FAMILIES.
WE UNDERSTAND THAT.
>> GRETA: JUST IMAGINE IF YOU
ARE FAMILY AT HOME AND YOU
EVAPORATE GOTTEN WORD, BUT YOUR
CHILD ISN'T HOME SO YOU KNOW
THAT YOUR CHILD WAS ONE OF THE
VICTIMS.
IT'S INEVITABLE.
IMAGINE THAT PAIN?
>> IT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
IT'S SOMETHING THAT NO ONE
REALLY EVER WANTS TO BEAR.
IT WAS HEARTBREAKING TO HAVE
TO -- HEAR THE PARENTS BEING
TOLD THEIR CHILDREN WERE NOT
COMING HOME.
IT WAS HEARTBREAKING FOR THE LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICERS TO GO IN TO
RESCUE AS MANY PEOPLE AS THEY
DID, AS MANY STAFFERS AS THEY
DID AND THEN ENCOUNTER WHAT THEY
DISCOVERED IN THOSE LAST TWO
CLASSROOMS.
>> GRETA: WAS THE SITUATIONS
WHERE THE KILLER KILLED EVERYONE
IN ONE ROOM AND KILLED AN ENTIRE
CLASS?
>> NO.
IT WASN'T LIKE THAT.
IT'S DIFFICULT TO TALK ABOUT.
BUT SUFFICE IT TO SAY, THERE
WERE DECEASED IN TWO CLASSROOMS
AND THE HALLWAY AND IT WAS A
HORRIFIC SCENE.
>> GRETA: WAS HE KNOWN TO LAW
ENFORCEMENT?
SOMETIMES THEIR NAMES ARE
FAMILIAR, THEY HAVE BEEN AROUND?
>> WE ARE LOOKING AT THAT.
WE HAVE A COMMAND INVESTIGATION
UNDERWAY.
WE HAVE BROUGHT IN MAJOR CRIME
DETECTIVES AND HAD THE NEWTOWN
POLICE DETECTIVES WORKING WITH
US.
WE ARE GOING TO ANSWER THOSE
QUESTIONS AND DO AN EXTENSIVE
BACKGROUND ON THE SHOOTER AND
ANSWER EVERY QUESTION ABOUT THE
HISTORY AND HISTORICAL -- ANY
HISTORICAL EVENTS THAT THIS
YOUNG MAN MAY HAVE BEEN INVOLVED
IN.
WE WILL LEAVE NO STONE UNTURNED?
>> GRETA: HAD THE MOTHER EVER
COMPLAINED ABOUT HIM OR SAID
ANYTHING THAT SHE WAS WORRIED
ABOUT HIM?
>> THERE IS NOTHING THAT SHOWED
THAT SOMETHING LIKE THIS COULD
OCCUR.
BUT, AGAIN, OUR INVESTIGATORS
WILL LOOK AT ALL OF THAT.
WE WILL INTERVIEW ALL THE
ADMINISTRATION OF THE SCHOOL,
SUPERINTENDENT, FRIENDS, FAMILY,
RELATIVES, CO-WORKERS.
THE LIST IS ENDLESS AND WE WILL
DO EVERYTHING WE CAN.
>> GRETA: ONE THING THAT IS
CURIOUS IS THAT, THAT I HAVE
READ OR HEARD THAT THE MOTHER
WAS FOUND DEAD AT HER HOME AND
SHE IS ALSO A TEACHER.
SO WAS SHE NOT TEACHING NOW?
DID SHE CALL IN SICK?
WHY WASN'T SHE AT SCHOOL?
DO YOU KNOW?
>> WE HAVEN'T IDENTIFIED ANYONE
YE
SO I AM IN A POSITION WHERE,
KITELL YOU WE HAVE A SECONDARY
SCENE WITH A DECEASED FEMALE, WE
TENTATIVELY HAVE IDENTIFIED.
THOSE ARE QUESTIONS THAT WE HAVE
AND HAVE TO ANSWER.
AT THIS POINT IN TIME, WE
HAVEN'T ANSWERED THEM.
>> GRETA: WAS THERE A SUBSTITUTE
TEACHENER THAT CLASSROOM?
>> THAT, I DON'T KNOW.
SORRY, I DON'T KNOW.
>> GRETA: RIGHT NOW, MEDICAL
EXAMINERS IN WITH THE CHILDREN
AND THE ADULTS?
>> YEAH, THE MEDICAL EXAMINER'S
AT THE SCENE WITH A TEAM.
AND HE HAS HIS TEAM IN PLACE.
THEY ARE GOING TO WORK RIGHT
THROUGH THE NIGHT AND DO
WHATEVER THEY NEED TO DO TO
IDENTIFY THE CHILDREN FOR THESE
FAMILIES.
>> GRETA: YOU KNOW, EVERY TIME I
HAVE COVERED THESE STORY, THE
POLICE OFFICER, LAW ENFORCEMENT,
THEY ARE ALL PARENTS.
YOU KNOW, THEY GO INTO THESE
SCENES AND IT'S LIKE -- IT'S
UNTHINKABLE AND UNSPEAKABLE.
THEY ALL HAVE KIDS.
THE ANAL OF THESE CHILDREN?
>> YEAH.
IT'S A VERY DIFFICULT SCENE FOR
THEM.
THE LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICERS WHO
HAVE ENTERED THE BUILDING, WE
HAVE PROVIDED THEM WITH
COUNSELING.
WE DID THAT SAME FOR THE FAMILY.
WE BROUGHT IN CLERGY.
IT IS HARD.
IT'S VERY HARD FORWARD LAW
ENFORCEMENT, THE FIRE SERVICE,
EMS PERSONNEL.
BUT CERTAINLY NOTHING LIKE THE
PARENTS ARE GOING THROUGH.
>> NO PARENT WANTS TO SEND HIS
CHILD TO A SCHOOL THAT IS
ESSENTIALLY A PRISON WITH A LOT
OF METAL DETECTORS AND SECURITY
AND EVERYTHING ELSE.
BUT I AM CURIOUS, THIS SCHOOL --
ANY SECURITY -- NOT THAT I AM IN
ANY WAY CONDEMNING THEM IF IT
HASN'T -- YOU KNOW, IT GOES BOTH
WAYS?
>> SUFFICE IT TO SAY THAT THE
SCHOOL WAS SECURE.
IT WAS VERY SECURE.
AND WE WILL CERTAINLY DETERMINE
EXACTLY HOW THE SHOOTER WAS ABLE
TO GAIN ACCESS.
>> GRETA: SECURE IN THE SENSE
THAT IF I TRIED TO GET IN,
SOMEBODY WOULD STOP ME?
THAT KIND OF SECURE?
SOMEONE HAS TO LET ME IN?
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
YOU COULD NOT HAVE GOTTEN IN.
>> GRETA: THANK YOU.
AND GOOD LUCK.
I KNOW IT'S TOUGH ON YOU AND
EVERYONE IN THE COMMUNITY,
ESPECIALLY THOSE OF THE DEAD.
THANK YOU, SIR.
OUR LIVE COVERAGE FROM
CONNECTICUT CONTINUES IN JUST
ONE MINUTE.
WE WILL HAVE THE LATEST
INFORMATION ON THE KILLER, PLUS
MORE ON THE LONG INVESTIGATION
THAT IS AHEAD.
FORMER DETECTIVE MARK FUHRMAN
WILL BE HERE.
"ON THE RECORD" LIVE FROM
NEWTOWN, STAY WITH US.
FROM NEWTOWN, STAY WITH US.
I JUST KNEW WE HAD TO GET IN
THERE AND IT IS IT GOING TO BE
OKAY AND YOU ARE GOING TO BE
ALL RIGHT I PULL WOULD A BOOK
SHELF AND WE WERE BARRICADED
AND DID YOU TELL THEM TO BE
QUIET.
NDID YOU WORRY ABOUT THAT.
>> I TOLD THEM TO BE
ABSOLUTELY QUIET.
BECAUSE I WAS SO AFRAID HE
WOULD COME IN AND HEAR US AND
START SHOOTING THE DOR.
WE HAVE TO BE ABSOLUTELY
QUIET.
AND WE HAVE.
THERE ARE BAD GOYS OUT THERE
NOW.
AND WE NEED TO WAIT FOR THE
GOOD GUYS.
I JUST WANTED US TO BE OKAY.
AND I AM SO SADDENED THRATHERE
ARE PIME IN THE SITUATION THAT
ARE NOT OKAY.
MY HEART GOES OUT TO WHO KNEW
THEM AND WAS PART OF THEIR
LIVES.    THE BOYS USE
Capital One Venture Miles
FOR THEIR ANNUAL FOOTBALL TRIP.
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE.
TRAGICALLY, THEIR DDY
GOT SACKED BY BLACKOUTS.
BUT IT'S OUR TRADITION!
THAT'S ROUGHING
THE CARD HOLDER.
BUT WITH
THE Capital One Venture Card
YOU GET DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE.
[ cheering ]
ANY FLIGHT, ANYTIME.
THE SCOREBOARD DOESN'T LIE.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET? HUT!
I HAVE ME ON MY FANTASY TEAM.
MONARCH OF MARKETING ANALYSIS.
WITH THE ABILITY TO IMPROVE
ROI THROUGH SEO
ALL BY COB.
AND YOU...RENT FROM NATIONAL.
BECAUSE ONLY NATIONAL LETS YOU
CHOOSE ANY CAR IN THE AISLE...
AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE
A FULL-SIZE OR ABOVE,
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
I'M GOING B-I-G.
[ Male Announcer ] GOOD CHOICE
BUSINESS PRO. GOOD CHOICE.
GO NATIONAL.
GO LIKE A PRO.
INTRODUCING CHASE LIQUID. CHOICE
BUSINCARD HASSLES? CHOICE.
THE RELOADABLE CARD
THAT'S EASY TO ACTIVATE
AND CAN BE USED RIGHT AWAY.
PLUS, YOU CAN LOAD
CASH OR CHECKS
AT ANY CHASE
DEPOSITFRIENDLY ATM
AND CHECKS RIGHT FROM
YOUR SMARTPHONE.
GET RID OF PREPAID PROBLEMS.
GET CHASE LIQUID.
>> WE A
>> WE ARE BACK LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THIS PRETTY NEW ENGLAND TOWN,
THE SCENE OF ONE OF THE
DEADLIEST SCHOOL SHOOTINGS IN
U.S. HISTORY.
FIRST REPORTS IDENTIFIED HIS
BROTHER, RYAN AS THE KILLER.
HOW DID THAT HAPPEN?
HOBOKEN EDITOR, CLAIR MOSES IS
HERE.
TELL ME, HOW DID THIS HAPPEN?
AND SECONDLY, YOU HAVE SPOKEN TO
FRIENDS OF RYE AP, HAVE YOU NOT?
>> I DID SPEAK TO FRIENDS OF
RYAN.
>> Reporter: I DID SPEAK TO
FRIENDS OF RYAN.
THE INTERNET STARTED PUBLISHING
RYAN'S PICTURE AND A LOT OF NEWS
OUTLETS STARTED KILL -- CALLING
HIM THE KILLER.
I WAS TALKING TO HIS FRIENDS,
SOME BY TEXT, SOME BY PHONE -- I
SPOKE TO THREE OF HIS FRIENDS
AND THEY ALL TOLD ME THEY THIS
SPOKEN TO HIM, BRIEFLY ON
FACEBOOK CHAT OR BY PHONE AND
THAT HE WAS, IN FACT, AT WORK
AND NOT THE KILLER.
IT WAS PHYSICALLY IMPOSSIBLE TO
HAVE BEEN IN NEWTOWN, WHILE HE
WAS AT WORK, TALKING ON THE
PHONE TO HIS FRIENDS.
[OVERLAPPING DIALOGUE]
>> Reporter: YES?
>> DO YOU KNOW -- DID ANY OF
RYAN'S FRIENDS -- HAVE THEY EVER
MET ADAM?
>> Reporter: NOT THE ONES THAT
I SPOKE.
TO THEY KNEW HE HAD A BROTHER
AND THAT IS ABOUT THE EXTENT OF
THEIR KNOWLEDGE.
THEY ALSO HAD VERY BRIEF
CONVERSATIONS WITH HIM TODAY
BECAUSE, AS YOU CAN IMAGINE, IT
WAS A VERY CRAZY DAY FOR HIM, SO
THEY JUST HAD A FEW MINUTES.
THEY KNEW HAD A BROTHER.
BUT NONE OF THEM SEEMED TO KNOW
ADAM.
>> GRETA: DID THEY KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT ADAM?
DID RYAN EVER SPEAK ABOUT ADAM
OR DESCRIBE ANYTHING USUAL OR
UNUSUAL, ABOUT HIS RELATIONSHIP,
WHERE HE LIVED, ANYTHING?
>> Reporter: THERE IS VERY,
VERY LITTLE KNOWLEDGE ABOUT
THAT.
ONE OF HIS FRIENDS THAT TELL ME
THAT IN FACT, HE HAD A BROTHER
AND THAT HE MIGHT HAVE BEEN A
LITTLE -- CHALLENGED.
I REPORTED THAT EARLIER IN THE
STORY THAT HE WAS
DEVELOPMENTALLY CHALLENGED.
BUT THAT IS ALL THE INFORMATION,
OTHER INFORMATION WAS VERY
SPARSE.
HIS FRIENDS DID NOT SEEM TO KNOW
HIS FAMILY VERY WELL.
OR THEY DID NOT MENTION THAT
TODAY.
>> GRETA: I TAKE IT BY MENTALLY
CHALLENGED, YOU DON'T HAVE ANY
MORE INFORMATION BEYOND THAT
VAGUE DESCRIPTION?
>> Reporter: I'M SORRY, GRETA?
>> GRETA: BEYOND THE VAGUE
DESCRIPTION "MENTALLY
CHALLENGED," YOU DON'T KNOW ANY
DESCRIPTION ABOUT ADAM?
>> Reporter: NOT ABOUT ADAM.
NOT ABOUT ADAM.
WE HEARD EARLIER TODAY THAT THE
CONFUSION MAY HAVE ARISEN
BECAUSE ADAM COULD HAVE HAD
RYAN'S IDENTIFICATIONO HIM.
RYAN TOLD ONE OF HIS FRIENDS
THAT THE CONFUSION AROSE THAT
WAY AND IT WAS PROBABLY ADAM
RATHER THAN HIMSELF.
BUT OTHER THAN THAT, VERY, VERY
LITTLE ABOUT ADAM HERE IN
HOBOKEN THIS EVENING.
>> GRETA: CLAIR, THANK YOU.
>> Reporter: THANK YOU.
>> GRETA: COMING UP, IT TOOK
ONLY MINUTES FOR THE KILLER TO
GUN DOWN 20 CHILDREN AND 6
ADULTS IN SCHOOL.
IN A MINUTE, YOU GET A CLOSER
LOOK AT HOW THIS HORRIBLE TERROR
UNFOLDED.
OUR LIVE COVERAGE FROM
CONNECTICUT CONTINUES.
THAT'S NEXT.
>> GRETA: HERE'S HOW TODAY'S
UNTHINKABLE TRAGEDY UNFOLDED.
>> BREAKING NEWS TO TELL YOU
RIGHT NOW.
THERE ARE REPORTSAVE SCHOOL
SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
HAD THIS IS AT THE SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL.
>> WE KNOW VERY FEW DETAILS.
BUT THIS IS WHAT WE CAN REPORT.
STATE POLICE ARE RESPONDED TO A
REPORT OF A SHOOTING AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, WHICH WE
UNDERSTAND IS KINDERGARTEN
THROUGH FOURTH GRADE.
>> HERE'S WHAT'S BEING REPORTED.
A DISPATCHER FROM THE NEWTOWN
VOLUNTARY AMBULANCE CORP
REPORTED ONE TEACHER HAS BEEN
TAKEN TO A NEARBY HOSPITAL,
POSSIBLY WITH A GUNSHOT WOUND.
>> JUST AHEAD OF HIM, IT IS
DIFFICULT TO SEE AT THIS POINT,
IS ONE OF THE S.W.A.T. TEAMS,
RESPONDING, ONE OF THE ARMORED
VEHICLES HEADING TO THAT SCHOOL,
RACING TO NEWTOWN FROM ALL OVER
THE STATE OF CONNECTICUT.
>> WE HAVE HAD NUMEROUS REPORTS
THAT THERE WAS ONE GUNMAN, MAYBE
TWO.
WE HAVE TWO REPORTS THAT ONE
GUNMAN MAY BE DEAD.
BUT YOU CAN UNDERSTAND, THIS IS
A FAST-MOVING, VERY FLUID
SITUATION AT THE SCHOOL.
>> I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT ON A
DAY LIKE TODAY... TO VIEW THIS
AS I KNOW THE PRESIDENT AS A
FATHER DOES AND I AS A FATHER
AND OTHERS WHO ARE PARENTS
CERTAINLY DO, WHICH IS TO.
FEEL ENORMOUS SYMPATHY FOR
FAMILIES THAT ARE AFFECTED AND
TO DO EVERYTHING WE CAN.
>> SOURCES ARE TELLING FOX NEWS
THAT 26 PEOPLE ARE DEAD AT THIS
TIME.
EIGHT ADULT, INCLUDING THE
SHOOTER AND 18 CHILDREN.
>> WHEN IT HAPPENED, I HEARD THE
GUNSHOTS AND SO -- THEY WERE
BOTH -- LIKE I SAID, IT WAS ONE
OF THOSE THING, WE ARE TRYING TO
SEE WHAT HAPPENS.
WE TELL THEM, ULTIMATELY, IT'S
GOING TO BE MUCH WORSE.
>> ONE SOURCE SUGGESTING THE
SHOOTER MAY HAVE BEEN A YOUNG
MAN, AS YOUNG AS 20 YEARS OLD.
HE MAY LIVE IN NEW JERSEY.
THERE MAY BE A SEPARATE
SITUATION THERE, A CRIME SCENE,
WHERE THEY KICKED DOWN THE DOOR
OF THAT PERSON'S HOME.
WE ARE TRYING TO CONFIRM THAT AT
THIS TIMEO AT THIS TIME.
WE DON'T BE THE IDENTITY OF THE
GUNMAN AND AT THIS POINT, HIS
CONNECTION TO THE SCHOOL.
>> THERE WERE SEVERAL FATALITIES
AT THE SCENE, BOTH STUDENTS AND
STAFF.
THERE IS NO INFORMATION,
RELATIVE TO THAT BEING RELEASED
AT THIS TIME, UNTIL WE HAVE MADE
COMPLETE AND PROPER
NOTIFICATION.
>> THERE ARE NO WORDS.
IT'S SHEER TERROR.
AND -- AND -- AND A SENSE OF
IMMEDIATE URGENCY AND... YOU
KNOW, TO GET TO YOUR CHILD --
AND TO BE THERE TO PROTECT THEM.
>> THE PRESIDENT IS SAID TO MAKE
SOME REMARKS ABOUT THE SHOOTING
TODAY.
LET'S TAKE A LISTEN.
>> THIS AFTERNOON, I SPOKE WITH
GOVERNOR MALLOY AND FBI DIRECTOR
MULLER.
I OFFERED GOVERNOR MALLOY MY
CONDOLENCES ON BEHALF OF THE
NATION AND MADE IT CLEAR, HE
WILL HAVE EVERY SINGLE RESOURCE
THAT HE NEEDS TO INVESTIGATE
THIS HEINOUS CRIME, CARE FOR THE
VICTIMS, COUNSEL THEIR FAMILIES.
>> AS HAS BEEN REPORTED, THRRN
FATALITIES, THERE WERE 18
CHILDREN THAT WERE PRONOUNCED
DEAD AT THE SCHOOL.
THERE WERE TWO THAT WERE
TRANSPORTED TO AREA HOSPITALS,
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT AREA
HOSPITALS AND SIX ADULTS,
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCENE, AT
THE SCHOOL.
>> REMEMBER THAT THIS HAPPENED
JUST OVER SIX HOURS AGO.
SO THERE IS A LOT OF EVIDENCE
STILL BEING PROCESSED, THE CRIME
SCENE STILL VERY ACTIVE AND
OTHER SCENES NOW BEING
INVESTIGATED, INCLUDING
APPARENTLY, THE HOME OF THE
SHOOTER'S MOTHER HERE IN
NEWTOWN, WHERE AN ADULT BODY WAS
FOUND, AS WELL AS ANOTHER
RESIDENT IN NEW JERSEY.
THERE ARE CONFLICTING REPORTS
ABOUT THE STATUS OF THE
SHOOTER'S FATHER AND CONFLICTING
REPORTS ON THE SHOOTER HIMSELF.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTH DAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS...:  KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
[SIGHING].
>> AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS, MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES TO HELPING
OUR CHILDREN FULFILL THEIR
DREAMS.
SO OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN
TODAY... FOR THE PARENTS AND
GRANDPARENTS, SISTERS AND
BROTHERS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN AND FOR THE FAMILIES OF
THE ADULTS WHO WERE LOST.
>> GRETA: SHEER TERROR, YOUNG
CHILDREN, PARENTS AND TEACHERS,
ALL WITNESSING THE TRAGEDY, THIS
HORRIBLE VIOLENCE.
>> DOESN'T EVEN SEEM REAL T.
JUST DOES NOT SEEM LIKE IT'S
EVEN POSSIBLE.
>> THERE ARE NO WORD, IT'S SHEER
TERROR AND -- AND -- A TEPEES OF
IMMEDIATE URGENCY AND...:  YOU
KNOW, TO GET TO YOUR CHILD AND
TO BE THERE TO PROTECT THEM.
>> I GOT AN EMERGENCY PHONE CALL
THAT THERE HAD BEEN A SHOOTING,
BUT THEY DIDN'T SAY WHERE AND
THE SCHOOLS WERE ON LOCKDOWN.
SO IMMEDIATELY AFTER THAT, I GOT
A TEXT FROM MACHINE WHO SAID
THERE WAS A SHOOTING AT A SCHOOL
ON SANDY HOOK -- AND I SAID, OH,
MY GOD, THAT'S DAN.
I WENT TO THE SCHOOL, THERE WERE
SOME OF THE SM HISTORICAL MOMS
THAT I KNEW AND I SAID, WHAT'S
GOING ON?
SHE SAID THE PRINCIPAL IS DEAD
AND CHILDREN CAME OUT WITH
BLOOD.
>> WE -- WE ARE COPING.
WE ARE TRYING TO FIND OUT WHAT'S
GOING ON.
IT'S A LITTLE NERVE RACKING.
AS YOU CAN TELL, BEHIND US, WE
DO HAVE A FEW MORE CARS PULLING
IN.
HOW MANY SHOOTERS?
HOW MANY PEOPLE ARE INJURED?
>> SHE WAS IN A SMALL CLASS, A
READING GROUP AND THEY STARTED
HEARING, I GUESS, BANGS AND...
AND GOT HER TEACHER, WHICH I AM
SO GRATEFUL FOR, THERE WAS A
SMALL GROUP, THEY RUSHED THE
KIDS INTO THE BATHROOM AND THEY
LOCKED THE DOOR AND THEY JUST
TOLD THE CHILDREN THAT IT WAS
HAMMERING AND TRIED TO KEEP THEM
CALM.
THE NEXT THING I KNOW -- BECAUSE
IT'S VERY HARD TO GET A COMPLETE
STORY.
THE NEXT THING I KNOW IS THAT
THE POLICE CAME AND THEY WERE
KNOCKING ON THE DOOR TO BE LET
OUT -- OF THE CLASSROOM.
AND WHEN THEY WERE, SHE HAD SEEN
GLASS AND BLOOD -- ONE CHILD WAS
COVERED IN BLOOD, BUT I
UNDERSTAND THAT CHILD IS SAFE.
>> LATER ON, AGAIN, SHE WAS
TALKING ABOUT HOW -- THE -- YOU
KNOW, WHILE SHE WAS WALKING DOWN
THE HALLWAY, THE POLICE TOLD
THEM TO CLOSE THEIR EYES
BECAUSE, OBVIOUSLY, IT WAS A
VERY SENSITIVE SCENE.
AND SHE SAID SHE HEARD GUNSHOTS
AND -- ACTUALLY, WHAT SHE TOLD
ME WAS -- IN THE BEGINNING, THE
INTERCOM CAME OUT AND SHE HEARD
A SCREAM ON THE INTERCOM, AROUND
THE SCHOOL.
AND THE INTERCOM WENT
IMMEDIATELY OFF.
I AM NOT SURE HOW IS HOW THE
SCHOOL GOT LOCKDOWN AND SHE DID
HEAR A SCREAM ON THE INTERCOM.
>> NOTHING MAKES SENSE LIKE
THIS, IT'S SENSELESS.
NO, IT DOESN'T.
OUR HEARTS ARE WITH EVERYBODY.
EVERY PARENT, EVERY MOTHER,
FATHER, MOTHER, GRANDFATHER,
GRANDMOTHER.
>> EVERYBODY SEEMS TO BE DOING
OKAY.
A COUPLE OF FRIENDS WE HAVEN'T
BEEN ABLE TO GET IN TOUCH WITH,
NO ANSWER.
WE HOPE EVERYTHING'S OKAY WITH
THEM.
>> GRETA: COMING UP, MORE LIVE
COVERAGE FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
FIND OUT WHY THE POLICE ARE
RIGHT NOW, INSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
FORMER DETECTIVE MARK FUHRMAN IS
HERE.
THAT'S NEXT.
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Sharable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>> TONIGHT THE INVESTIGATION
IN THE CONNECTICUT MASS
SHOOTING IS ONLY BEGINNING.
THE HOMICIDE DETECTIVE MARK
FURMAN JOINS US.
>> GOOD EVENING.
>> MARK, YOU AND I GO BACK A
LONG TIME TALKING ABOUT ALL OF
THESE CASES.
THIS ONE TONIGHT, RIGHT NOW AS
WE TALK.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER INSIDE OF
THAT CLASSROOM, AND BODIES
STILL IN THE CLASSROOM AND
TRYING TO DETERMINE IDEPTITY.
I CAN ONLY IMAGINE HOW
DIFFICULT IT IS FOR THE POLICE
AND MEDICAL EXAMINER AND
FAMILIES AND EVERYTHING.
THIS HAS TO BE DONE, DOESN'T
IT?
>> IT DOES HAVE TO BE DONE,
GRETA AND UNFORTUNATELY, I CAN
IMAGINE WHAT IT LOOKS LIKE AND
YOU TRY TO PUT THAT OUT OF
YOUR MIND.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER AND
FORENSIC PERSONNEL HAVE TO
BLUE PRIPT THE ROOM WHERE EACH
AND EVERY PERSON IS.
ALL EVIDENCE HAS TO BE
PHOTOGRAPHED BEFORE IT IS
DISTURBED AND YOU HAVE TO
NUMBER AND THE POSITIONS OF
EACH BODY.
EACH BODY HAS TO BE PROCESSED
AND EXAMINED BY THE CORONER
AND FORENSICALLY AND
DOCUMENTED AND EVIDENCE
COLLECTED AND THEN, AND ONLY
THEN CAN YOU REMOVE EACH BODY
ONE AT A TIME.
>> YOU KNOW, I THINK OF THE
FAMILIES TONIGHT.
THEY HAVEN'T GOT KNOW OFFICIAL
WORD THEIR CHILD IS DEAD OR A
LOVED ONE OR WIFE OR MOTHER.
BUT IF YOU ARE SITTING AT HOME
AND YOU ARE EXPECTING YOUR
CHILD TO BE HOME OR EXPECTED
YOUR WIFE OR MOTHER OR FATHER
TO BE HOME AND THAT PERSON
HASN'T SHOWN UP.
YOU OBVIOUSLY KNOW THAT YOU
ARE -- YOUR FAMILY MEMBER WAS
A VICTIM AND A LOT OF PEOPLE
ARE THINKING WHY IN THE WORLD
GOING ON.
WE KNOW WHO THE SHOOTER IS.
HE SHOT HIMSELF IN THE HEAD
AND THERE IS IT A RISK OF A
CO-DEFENDANT OR SOMEONE WHO
HELPED HIM AND YOU WILL HAVE
TO PUT A CASE TOGETHER; IS
THAT WHY THEY DO THIS?
>> YOU HAVE TO DOCUMENT IT,
BECAUSE IT IS WHAT YOU NEED TO
DO TO REALLY CREATE A HISTORY
OF THE INSTENT.
FOR LEGAL PURPOSES AND
CERTAINLY THERE COULD BE CIVIL
ACTIONS IF THERE IS NOT
CRIMINAL.
YOU HAVE TO REMEMBER THAT THIS
SUSPECT WAS DESCRIBED AS
SOMEONE WHO MIGHT HAVE MENTAL
PROBLEMS AND INCAPACITY AS FAR
AS HIS MENTAL STATE HE
HAVE BEEN FORMULATED BY
SOMEONE ELSE AND GUIDED AND
PROVIDED WITH INFORMATION AND
A CONSPIRACY, YOU KNOW.
IT IS REALLY WHAT I AM TALKING
ABOUT AND SOMEBODY COULD HAVE
PUT HIM UP AND GAVE HIM
INFORMATION AND COMPLETED THE
CONSPIRACY.
AND THEN YOU WOULD NEED TO
PROSECUTE THAT INDIVIDUAL.
SO IT NEEDS TO BE DONE BECAUSE
THIS EARLY IN THE
INVESTIGATION, YOU COUNTY
DON'T KNOW -- WHAT YOU HAVE
EXCEPT FOR THE VICTIMS.
>> WE ARE GETTING A LITTLE BIT
OF AN IDEA WHO HE WAS.
AND THE NEW YORK TIMES AND
REPORTING ABOUT HOW SOCIALLY
ACWARD HE HIGH SCHOOL.
AND FEW FREPPEDS AND HE DIDN'T
CENTER A BOOK BOOK -- FACE
BOOK PAGE WE ARE GETTING A
GLIMPSE OF HIM TONIGHT .
BUT THE DETECTIVES.
THEY HAVE TO DIG DEEPER, ARE
THEY NOT?
>> THEY ARE GOING TO DIG
DEEPER FOR WEEKS AND MAYBE
LONGER THAN THAT.
THEY WILL DO AN AUTOPSY ON HIS
MIND AND HIS LIFE AS WELL AS
HIS BODY.
THEY ARE GOING TO FIGURE OUT
WHO HE WAS TALKING TO AND WHAT
HIGH WAS SAYING AND TALK TO
FRIENDS AND FAMILY AND ANYBODY
ON THE COMPUTER AND WEB SITES
AND ANYTHING HE PUT OUT OR
WROTE.
ANYTHING THAT HE THREATENED.
THEY ARE GOING TO FIND OUT
JUST EXACTLY HOW MANY FLAGS
THERE WERE AND THAT IS REALLY
ONLY WAY TO GO BACK WARDS AND
TRY TO PREVENT AN INCIDENT IS
TO CONTROL THE INDIVIDUAL WITH
THE IDEA AND MOTIVATION TO DO
AS HEINOUS AS THIS.
NDO YOU EVER GET USED TO THE
INVESTIGATION .
20 CHILDREN.
THEY ARE LIKE FIVE OR 10 YEARS
OLD.
IT SEEMS LIKE THE WORST OF THE
WORST.
AND AS A DETECTIVE, DO YOU
EVER, CAN YOU DO THIS?
AND HOW DO YOU GO THROUGH
THYSELF THINGS?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, THERE IS NO
WAY THAT ANYBODY CAN PREPARE
THEMSELVES FOR A CHILD'S
HOMICIDE.
JUST IN THE SINGULAR SENSE.
THIS, THE AMOUNT OF
RECOMMEND'RE VICTIMS AND THEIR
AGE IS BEYOND OVERWHELMING.
AND I AM SURE THAT YOU KNOW,
DETECTIVES AND FORENSIC
PERSONNEL.
THEY HAVE TO DETACH THEMSELVES
FOR THAT PERIOD OF TIME TO DO
THEIR JOB.
THIS IS IT A HORRIFIC SCENE
AND A HORRIFIC CRIME THAT NO
ONE WILL GET OVER AND NO ONE
SEEING THE SCENE WILL BE QUITE
THE SAME.
>> MARK, THANK YOU FOR JOINING
US TONIGHT.
>> STRAIGHT AHEAD, YOU WILL
HEAR THE CHILLING RADIO CALLS
AS POLICE LEARNED ABOUT THE
MASS SHOOTING, THAT'S NENENENENE
>> GRETA: THIS SCHOOL MASSACRE
SHOCKING EVEN TOCHL PEER YENSED
POLICE OFFICERS.
WE HAVE THE CHILLING RADIO
CALLS AS POLICE FIRST LEARNED
ABOUT THE SLOOT SHOOTHING
SPREE.
LISTEN TO THIS.
>> CALLERS INDICATING SHE
THINKS SOMEONE IS SHOOTING IN
THE BUILDING.
THE ANSWER I!,óç... THE ANSWER S
FRONT GLASS HAS BEEN -- THEY'RE
UNSURE WHY.
THE INDIVIDUAL I HAVE ON THE
PHONE IS CONTINUING TO HEAR
WHAT YOU BELIEVES TO BE
GUNFIRE.
>> AND RIGHT.
RIGHT.
>> OTHER UNITS.
>> THE SHOOTING APPEARS TO
HAVE STOPPED.
THE SCHOOL IS IN LOCK DOWN.
>> ROGER.
>> REPORTS THE TEACHER SAW TWO
RUNNING PAST THE BUILDING PAST
THE GYM, WHICH WOULD BE REAR,
I THINK, NEAR THE SHOOTING.
>> YOUR REQUESTED TO STAY.
I WILL NEED TWO AMBULANCES AT
THIS TIME.
>> JUST RECEIVED A CALL.
WE HAVE ONE IN ROOM ONE WHODdl
RECEIVED A SHOT TO THE FOOT.
OTHER INJURIES AT THIS TIME.
>> OKAY.
BODIES HERE.
>> I THINK IS THAT AN EMF?I#
>> AT THE... DRIVEWAY.
BETWEEN THE FIRE HYDRANT.
>> IS THERE ANYONE?
>> WE'VE GOT ONE SUSPECT DOWN.
BE ADVISED WE HAVE MULTIPLE
WEAPONS INCLUDING LONG RIFLES
AND SHOTGUNS.
WE NEED OFFICERS HERE.
ASAP.
>> WE JUST HAD A CASE BROUGHT
TO US BY A POLICE OFFICER.
>> WOULD YOU CONTACT A COUPLE
OF OUR OFFICERS TO MAN THE
BACK HALL SO WE CAN PUT PEOPLE
INSIDE OF THERE?
>> ONE PATIENT TRANSPORTED TO
THE HOSPITAL.
>> ANOTHER VEHICLE NOT SECURE.
>> NOW 401, 444 ROUTE.
>> MAKE CONTACT WITH THE
COMMANDING OFFICER AT THE
SCENE JUST TO ENSURE THAT THE
AREA YOU'RE GOING INTO HAVE
BEEN CLEARED.
>> OKAY.
WHO IS THE COMMANDING OFFICER
HERE?
>> OFFICER IN THE BACK.
>> ROGER.
>> IT'S OVER BEHIND.
ROGER THERE.
>> ROGER.
>> JERSEY PLACE.
A COUPLE OCCUPANTS.
NOT SURE WHERE I GOT CUTOFF ON
THE CALLER.
>> THIS IS STILL AN ACTIVE
SCENE.
KEEP THE AREA CLEAN.
>> WE'RE INBOUND IN THAT
LOCATION WITH ER SUPPORT.
IS THERE A LINK UP POINT?
>> ROGER.
CLOSET IN THE KITCHEN.
THEY HAVE SOME VICTIMS.
LET US KNOW, WE'LL CALL THE
NUMBER SO THEY'LL KNOW YOU'RE
COMING.
>> ONE OF THE PLACES IS THE
KITCHEN.
THERE IS A TEACHER IN THERE.
>> THE CAR RENTAL, LANE, NEW
JERSEY.
>> THERE IS A GUY ON THE END
OF THE ROAD.
KEEP THE ROAD CLEAR, WE NEED
TO GET EMF OUT OF HERE, KEEP
IT HERE.
>> NEWTOWN OFFICERS AT THE
SCENE.
THE SCENE SCENE IS NOT ACTIVE,
NOT ACTIVE AT THIS TIME.
>> GRETA: STRAIGHT AHEAD ONE
MURDER VICTIM IS THE SCHOOL
PRINCIPAL.
SHE TURNED ON THE P.A.SYSTEM
AS EVENTS WERE UNFOLDING.
YOU'LL HEAR WHAT HAPPENED AS A
RESULT, THAT IS NEXT.
[ Male Announcer ]
RED LOBSTER'S
HITTING THE STREETS
TO TELL REAL PEOPLE ABOUT
OUR NEW 15 UNDER $15 MENU.
OH MY GOODNESS!
OH MY GOSH,
THIS LOOKS AMAZING!
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR NEW MAINE STAYS!
15ENTREES UNDER $15,
SEAFOOD, CHICKEN AND MORE!
OOTHE TILAPIAWITH ROASTEDEGETAB!
I'M ACTUALLY LOOKING AT
THE WO GRILLED CHICKEN
WITH PORTOBELLO WINE SAUCE.
AT PORK CHOP
WAS GREAT!
NO MORE
FAST FOOD FRIDAY'S!
WE'RE GOING TO GO
TO RED LOBSTER.
YEP.
[ Male Announcer ]
COME TRY OUR NEW MENU
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
SALAD, SANDWICHES, AND MORE.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
TO THE BEST VACATION
SP(ALL) THE GULF!
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHICH OF
OUR GREAT STATES FOLKS VISIT.
MISSISSIPPI,
ALABAM
LOUISIANA
OR FLORIDA,
THEY'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
SHAUL, YOUR ALABAMA
HOSPITALITY IS INCREDIBLE.
THANKS, KAREN.
LOVE YOUR MISSISSIPPI OUTDOORS.
I VOTE FOR YOUR
FLORIDA BEACHES, DAWN.
BILL, THIS LOUISIANA
SEAFOOD IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR ON THE GULF,
WE'VE DECIDED TO PUT
ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
NOW IS THE PERFECT TIME TO
VISIT ANYONE OF OUR STATES.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE, GO FISHING
OR JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
WE'VE GOT COASTLINE TO EXPLORE
AND WILDLIFE TO PHOTOGRAPH.
AND THERE'S WORLD CLASS DINING
WITH OUR WORLD FAMOUS SEAFOOD.
SO FOR A GREAT VACATION
THIS YEAR, COME TO THE GULF.
ITS ALL FABULOUS BUT
I GIVE FLORIDA THE EDGE.
RIGHT AFTER MISSISSIPPI.
YOU MEAN ALABAMA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
THIS INVITATION IS
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP
AND ALL OF US WHO
CALL THE GULF HOME.
>> GRETA: 20 SMALL CHILDREN,
SIX ADULTS MASSACRED IN AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
ONE OF THEM, THE SCHOOL PRANCE
PAL.
BUT BEFORE SHE WAS GUNNED DOWN
SHE TURNED ON TD PUBLIC
ADDRESS SYSTEM.
THAT MAY HAVE SAVED LIVES.
GARY, NICE TO SEE YOU.
>> THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
>> YOU SPOKE TO THE NIECE OF
THE PRINCIPAL.
>> YES.
ON A CONFERENCE CALL WITH ONE
OF MY EDITORS.
>> GRETA: WHAT DID SHE SAY?
>> SHE RELATED JUST A
THOUGHTFUL, BEAUTIFUL PERSON
HER AUNT WAS.
HOW SHE REMEMBERED HER AND
THAT SHE SHARED A STORY SHE'D
HEARD HOW HER AUNT SAVED LIVES
BY PUSHING FOR FOLKS BACK INTO
THE CONFERENCE ROOM.
AND HITTING THE P.A.TO HEAR
WHAT IS GOING ON TO GET
SOMETIME TO GET INTO A SAFE
PLACE.
>> GRETA: SHOOTING GOING
THROUGHOUT THE SCHOOL?
THEY REACHED THE WHOLE SCHOOL?
>> I FOUND INFORMATION WE'VE
HAD CONFIRMED, IT'S A STORY
THAT THE RELATIVE HAS RELAYED
TO US.
SO WE HAVEN'T CONFIRMED THAT
WITH OFFICIAL SOURCES.
BUT IT WAS A STORY THAT THE
RELATIVE, THE NIECE OF THE
PRINCIPAL SHARED WITH US.
>> GRETA: IT'S A TERRIBLE
STORY.
TERRIBLE FOR THE COMMUNITY.
YOU LIVE HERE, GREW UP HERE.
>> YES.
I ARE HAVE FAMILY IN NEWTOWN.
AND IT'S -- IT'S JUST
DEVASTATING.
YOU KNOW?
NO ONE COULD HAVE EVER
IMAGINED SOMETHING LIKE THIS
WOULD HAPPEN ANYWHERE, OR
HERE.
AND THERE IS A REAL SADNESS,