♪
>>  OH, GOD FULL OF
COMPASSION, GRANT PERFECT
PEACE IN YOUR PRESENCE AMONG
THE HOLY AND THE PURE, TOLE
SOULS OF ALL OF OUR LOVED ONES
THAT PERRISHED ON THAT
HORRIBLE DAY.
THEY HAVE GONE TO THEIR
ETERNAL HOME, MESSENGER OF
MERCY WE BESEECH YOU, REMEMBER
ALL OF THEIR WORTHY AND
RIGHTEOUS DEEDS THAT THEY
PERFORMED IN THE LAND OF THE
LIVING.
MAY THEIR SOULS BE BOUND UP IN
THE BOND OF LIFE ETERNAL.
THERE IS NO DEATH, JUST
TRANSFORMATION.
MAY THEY REST IN PEACE.
AND LET US SAY AMEN.
>> AMEN.
>> PLEASE BE SEATED.
>>  AND LET US UNITE OUR
HEARTS IN PRAYER, OH GOD OF
LOVE AND MERCY, WE COME BEFORE
YOU THIS NIGHT WITH BROKEN
HEARTS.
WE OFFER YOU OUR TEARS AND OUR
PAIN, OUR ANGER AND OUR
SORROW.
OH, LORD, THERE WAS A HOLE SO
LARGE, WE WONDER IF EVEN YOU
IN YOUR GREATNESS CAN FILL IT
AS WE GRIEVE AND MOURN FOR
THOSE WHO ARE LOST.
EACH LIGHT THAT SITS BEFORE US
IS A LIGHT THAT'S BEEN LOST TO
OUR WORLD.
SO MANY INNOCENTS, SO MANY
BRAVE, LORD, ALL WE CAN DO IS
THROW OURSELVES UPON YOUR
TENDER MERCIES, TRUSTING THAT
YOU HEAR OUR PRAYERS.
WE KNOW THOSE WHO ARE LOST
BECAUSE THEY'RE OURS, LORD,
NOT NAMES ON SOME LIST, BUT
OUR MOTHERS, OR SISTERS, OUR
BROTHERS, OR FRIENDS, KINDRED
ALL BECAUSE IF WE DID NOT KNOW
THEM OURSELVES, WE KNOW
SOMEONE WHO DID.
AND SO, WE PRAY, LORD FOR ALL
THE SOULS LOST AND ALL THE
FAMILIES AND FRIENDS WHO ARE
SO TORN BY GRIEF, FOR IN THIS
MOMENT WE ARE ALL YOUR
CHILDR
CHILDREN, A FAMILY RELATED BY
YOUR LOVE.
SO HELP US TO CARE FOR THESE
FAMILIES IN THEIR SORROW AND
FOR EACH OTHER IN OURS.
MAY THEY FEEL THE HEALING
EMBRACE OF A NEIGHBORHOOD, A
TOWN, A STATE, A NATION, A
WORLD.
HELP US TO FOREVER REMEMBER
THAT WE EMBRACE THE GRIEVING
AS OUR OWN AND BRING US
TOGETHER AS ONE FAMILY TO LIVE
TOGETHER IN PEACE AND AMITY.
HELP US TO SHARE THE LIGHTS
THAT STAND BEFORE US.
HELP US TO CARRY THEM OUT INTO
THIS WORLD AND SHARE IT WITH A
WORLD SO IN SORROW AND SO IN
NEED.
WE PRAY ALL OF THIS IN THE
NAME OF YOUR LOVE AS WE ALL
SAY, AMEN.
>>  THIS IS AN INTERFAITH
SERVICE AT NEWTOWN HIGH
SCHOOL.
MEMBERS OF CLERGY, VARIOUS
CHURCHES, SYNAGOGUES, PLACES
OF FAITH THROUGHOUT THE
REGION.
NEXT UP, KATHY ADAMS SHEPHERD,
DIRECTOR OF EPISCOPAL CHURCH
WILL READ PSALM 23, ALL OF
THESE KILLED FRIDAY, THE 26
INSIDE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
WE INVITE YOU TO JOIN WITH US
IN PSALM 23, IN ANY WAY THAT
YOU KNOW IT IN YOUR HEART.
IT DOESN'T HAVE TO BE THE
WORDS HERE.
>> THE LORD IS MY SHEPARD, HE
SHALL MOTT WANT LEADETH
BESIDES THE STILL WATERS, HE
RESTORES MY SOUL.
HE LEADETH ME IN THE PATH OF
THE RIGHTEOUSNESS FOR HIS
NAMESAKE, YEA, THOUGH I WALK
THROUGH THE VALLEY OF THE
SHADOW OF DEATH, I WILL FEAR
NO EVIL FOR THOU ART WITH ME,
THY ROD AND THY STAFF, THEY
COMFORT ME.
THOU PREPARES THE TABLE BEFORE
ME IN THE PRESENCE OF MINE
ENEMY.
THOU ANOINTEST MY HEAD WITH
OIL, MY CUP RUNETH OVER.
SURELY GOODNESS AND MERCY
SHALL FOLLOW ME ALL THE DAYS
OF MY LIFE AND I WILL DWELL IN
THE HOUSE OF THE LORD FOREVER.
LET US PRAY.
GOD IN HEAVEN, WE THANK YOU
FOR YOUR PRESENCE WITH US HERE
ON EARTH.
WE KNOW THAT THE CHILDREN WHO
WERE LOST IN THE TRAGEDY FIRST
BELONGED TO YOU BEFORE THEY
BELONGED TO US.
AND WE COMMIT THEIR SOULS TO
YOU, TO YOUR LOVING ETERNAL
CARE.
WE THANK YOU, LORD THAT THEY
ARE NOW IN A PLACE OF NO MORE
SICKNESS, NO MORE SADNESS, NO
MORE SUFFERING AND NO MORE
SORR
SORROW AND FINALLY NO MORE SIN
IN THE PRESENCE OF YOU, HIS
SAVIOR AND OURS.
DEAR LORD, AS WE LIVE THE
CHILDREN THAT WE HAVE LOST IN
YOUR HANDS, WE ASK THAT BY
YOUR GRACE YOU WOULD EMPOWER
US TO BLESS AND COMFORT THE
CHILDREN WHO ARE STILL HERE IN
OUR HANDS.
PLEASE BE WITH THEM IN A
SPECIAL WAY AS THEY GRIEVE THE
LOSS OF SIBLINGS AND FRIENDS.
LIFE WILL NEVER BE THE SAME
FOR THEM AND YET, WE ASK THAT
YOU WOULD HELP THESE PRECIOUS
LITTLE ONES TO CARRY THE
SPIRITS OF THEIR LOST LOVED
ONES IN THEIR HEARTS AS THEY
GO ALONG LIVING THEIR LIVES TO
ITS FULLEST ACCORDING TO YOUR
WILL FOR EACH OF THESE GIRLS
AND BOYS.
AND, LORD, WE ASK MOST OF ALL
THAT YOU WOULD USE US TO BE A
SOURCE OF YOUR HEALING IN THE
MIDST OF THEIR WOUNDS, THAT
YOU WOULD USE THOSE OF US
WHOSE CHILDREN ARE TRYING TO
HOPE AS A SOURCE OF YOUR HOPE
IN THE MIDST OF ANY
HOPELESSNESS, AS YOU ARE THE
GOD OF HOPE.
USE US TO REPLACE THEIR
ANXIETY WITH YOUR PEACE AS YOU
ARE THE GOD OF PEACE.
AND PLEASE, FILL THEIR HEARTS
WITH THE SENSE OF YOUR LOVE,
YOUR PRESENCE, YOUR POWER AND
MOST OF ALL, A SENSE OF YOUR
CARE, NOT KNOWING WHAT THE
FUTURE HOLDS, BUT KNOWING THAT
YOU HOLD IT AS YOU HOLD THESE
PRECIOUS LITTLE ONES WHO ARE
STILL WITH US TODAY IN YOUR
HANDS THROUGH OUR HANDS.
AND, LORD, WE ASK IN THE NAME
OF THE ONE WHO SAYS, UNLESS WE
BECOME LIKE LITTLE CHILDREN,
WE CANNOT ENTER THE KINGDOM OF
GOD.
MAKE US ALL CHILD-LIKE AND NOT
CHILDISH IN OUR THOUGHTS, IN
OUR WORDS, IN OUR ATTITUDES
AND ACTIONS AND BEHAVIORS, NOT
ONLY BEFORE OTHERS, BUT BEFORE
YOU THAT WE MAY LOOK TO YOU
FOR BETTER DAYS AHEAD AND THAT
WE MAY FULFILL YOUR PURPOSE
FOR US ON THIS EARTH.
WE PRAY ALL OF THIS IN THE
NAME OF OUR PRECIOUS LORD AND
SAVIOR, JESUS, AMEN.
>>  THAT WAS THE PASTOR FROM
THE NEW HOPE COMMUNITY CHURCH.
THIS IS AN INTERFAITH VIGIL,
PRAYER SERVICE REMEMBERING THE
26 PEOPLE KILLED AND THERE YOU
SEE CANDLES IN FRONT OF THE
PODIUM THERE, 26 OF THEM TO
REMEMBER THE 20 CHILDREN AND
SIX ADULTS KILLED IN SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
NEXT A READING FROM THE KORAN
AND A PRAYER FROM EL HADYA
ISLAMIC CENTER AND PRAYER FOR
THE EMERGENCY RESPONDERS FROM
THE VISITATION OF SPIRITUAL
GROWTH, JAMES SIBLEY NEWTOWN
UNITED BAPTIST CHURCH.
YOU SEE THE PRESIDENT LOOKING
ON IN THE AUDITORIUM.
♪
>> .
[SINGING PRAYER]
♪
>>  IN THE NAME OF GOD,
COMPASSIONATE AND MERCIFUL.
THE MUSLIM COMMUNITY IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, AND THE
NATION JOIN WITH OUR FELLOW
AMERICANS GRIEVING FOR THOSE
WHO DIED IN THIS SENSELESS
TRAGEDY AND PRAYING FOR THEM
AND THEIR FAMILIES.
WE ASK GOD TO GRANT THOSE LOST
A SPECIAL PLACE IN PARADISE
AND WE ASK THEIR FAMILIES TO
BE GRANTED THE STRENGTH TO
ENDURE THE UNENDURABLE.
IT IS IN SUCH TIMES OF ALMOST
UNBEARABLE LOSS THAT WE SEEK
THE COMFORT WITH OUR CREATOR
AND THAT ARTIFICIAL DIVISIONS
OF FAITH FALL AWAY TO REVEAL A
NATION OF MOTHERS, FATHERS,
BROTHERS AND SISTERS, SONS AND
DAUGHTERS, ALL UNITED IN A
DESIRE TO BRING RENEWED HOPE.
THE KORAN, TEXT TELLS US THAT
GOD'S MERCY AND COMPASSION ARE
WITHOUT LIMITS AND ALWAYS
AVAILABLE FOR THOSE WHO ASK.
GOD SAYS WHEN MY SERVANTS
QUESTION YOU ABOUT ME, TELL ME
THAT I AM HERE.
I ANSWER THE PRAYER OF EVERY
PERSON WHO CALLS ON ME.
CHAPTER 2, VERSE 186.
THE KORAN, IN THE KORAN GOD
ALSO SAYS GIVE GLAD TIDINGS TO
THOSE WHO ENDURE THE PATIENCE,
WHO WHEN AFFLICTED WITH
CALAMITY SAY, WE BELONG TO GOD
AND TO HIM WE SHALL RETURN.
SUCH ARE THE PEOPLE ON WHOM
THERE ARE BLESSINGS AND MERCY
FROM GOD, CHAPTER 2, VERSE 155
AND 157.
SO LET US ALL OF EVERY FAITH,
OF EVERY BACKGROUND, PRAY FOR
GOD'S COMFORT AT THIS TIME OF
UNBREAKABLE--
HEART BREAKING TRAGEDY.
WITH EVERY DIFFICULTY THERE IS
EASE, BARELY WITH EVERY
DIFFICULTY THERE IS EASE.
CHAPTER 94 VERSE 1 THROUGH 5,
5 THROUGH 6.
>> A PRAYER FOR THE FIRST
RESPONDERS, LET US PRAY.
HOLY GOD, MANY OF THESE MEN
AND WOMEN YOU CALLED INTO
SERVICE WHEN THEY WERE JUST
CHILDREN.
THEY WANTED TO BE POLICE
OFFICERS AND FIREFIGHTERS AND
CARE FOR THOSE THAT WERE IN
NEED, LORD.
YOU GAVE THEM GIFTS FOR THEIR
LIFE TO SERVE.
YOU ASKED THEM TO PAY A HIGH
PRICE FOR ALL THE SKILLS THAT
THEY HAVE BEEN GIVEN, FOR THE
STRENGTH THAT THEY HAVE.
YOU EQUIPPED THEM, YOU GAVE
THEM A WILLINGNESS TO LEARN,
TO TRAIN, TO STUDY.
YOU GAVE THEM A WILLINGNESS TO
SERVE IN THE MIDDLE OF THE
NIGHT WHEN THE CALL WOULD COME
IN AND YOU GAVE THEM THE
WILLINGNESS TO RESPOND WHEN
THIS TOWN NEEDED THEM THE
MOST.
LORD WE THANK YOU FOR THOSE IN
THIS TOWN THAT RESPONDED, BUT
WE THANK YOU ALSO FOR THOSE
THROUGHOUT THE STATE THAT CAME
WHEN THE NEED WAS GIVEN.
WE THANK YOU, LORD, FOR THEIR
GIFTS AND THEIR STRENGTH AND
THEIR COURAGE.
SO WE ASK YOU, LORD, TO WALK
WITH THEM IN THE DAYS AHEAD,
TO SURROUND THEM WITH YOUR
ANGELS.
TO GIVE THEM PEOPLE WHO WILL
LISTEN TO THEIR STORY, TO
LISTEN TO WHAT THEY SAW THAT
WAS NOT FOR ANYONE TO EVER S
SEE.
LORD, WE PLACE EACH AND EVERY
ONE OF THESE MEN AND WOMEN IN
YOUR CARE, BUT WE WILL BE
FAITHFUL TO THEM.
WE WILL CARE FOR THEM.
WE WILL CONTINUE TO EQUIP THEM
AND WE WILL KEEP THEM EVER IN
OUR PRAYERS.
AMEN.
>> .
>> Bret: LISTENING LIVE TO THE
INTERFAITH VIGIL AT NEWTOWN
HIGH SCHOOL, IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT REMEMBERING THE 26
PEOPLE KILLED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL ON FRIDAY,
20 OF THEM CHILDREN.
NEXT WE'LL HEAR A READING AND
PRAYER FROM THE BAHIGH
TRADITION AND JOHN WOODALL AND
COUNSELORS, CLERGY AND CARE
GIVERS FROM ECUMENICAL
CHAPLAIN OF THE LUTHREN HOME.
>>  FOR THE MOTHERS, FATHERS,
BROTHERS, SISTERS,
GRANDPARENTS, FOR ALL OF YOU
TODAY, THIS IS A, PART OF A
SACRED TEXT FROM THE BAHIGH
FAITH WRITTEN AS A LETTER TO A
MOTHER MOURNING FOR HER CHILD
AND I ADAPTED IT FOR THIS
EVENING.
>> ALTHOUGH THE LOSS OF A
CHILD IS INDEED HEART BREAKING
AND BEYOND THE LIMITS OF HUMAN
ENDURANCE, AS ONE WHO KNOWS
AND UNDERSTANDS, IS ASSURED
THAT THE CHILD HAS NOT BEEN
LOST, BUT RATHER, HAS STEPPED
FROM THIS WORLD INTO ANOTHER
AND YOU WILL FIND THEM IN THE
DIVINE REALM.
THAT REUNION SHALL BE FOR
ETERNITY, WHILE IN THIS WORLD
SEPARATION IS INEVITABLE AND
BRING WITH IT A BURNING GRIEF.
PRAISE BE UNTO GOD THAT THOU
HAS FAITH, IS TURNING THY FACE
TOWARD THE EVERLASTING KINGDOM
AND BELIEVETH IN THE EXISTENCE
OF A HEAVENLY WORLD.
BE NOT DISCONSULATE, DO NOT
LANGUISH, DO NOT SIGH, NEITHER
WAIL MORE WEEP, FOR EDUCATION
AND MOURNING DEEPLY AFFECT THE
SOUL, THEIR SOUL IN THE DIVINE
REALM.
>> THAT BELOVED CHILD
ADDRESSED FROM THE HIDDEN
WORLD, OH, THOU KIND MOTHER
AND FATHER, THANK DIVINE
PROVIDENCE THAT I HAVE BEEN
FREED FROM A SMALL AND GLOOMY
CAGE AND LIKE THE BIRDS OF THE
MEADOWS HAVE SOARED TO THE
DIVINE WORLD, A WORLD WHICH IS
SPACIOUS, EVER JOYOUS,
THEREFORE, LAMENT NOT, OH,
MOTHER AND FATHER, AND BE NOT
GRIEVED.
I AM NOT OF THE LOST, NOR HAVE
I BEEN OBLITERATED AND
DESTROYED.
I'VE SHAKEN OFF THE MORTAL
FORM AND HAVE RAISED MY BANNER
IN THE SPIRITUAL WORLD.
FOLLOWING THIS SEPARATION IS
EVER LASTING COMPANIONSHIP.
THOU SHALT FIND ME IN THE
HEAVEN OF THE LORD IMMERSED IN
AN OCEAN OF LIGHT.
>> GOD, WE'D CALL YOU BY MANY
NAMES.
GREAT SPIRIT, HIGHER POWER,
DIVINE ONE.
BUT HOWEVER WE ADDRESS YOU,
YOU ARE ALWAYS FATHER AND
MOTHER TO US ALL, AND WE ARE
YOUR CHILDREN, WE ARE YOUR
FAMI
FAMILY.
WE ASK YOUR BLESSING, LORD,
UPON THE COUNSELORS AND CLERGY
AND THE CARE GIVERS AMONG US,
THEY HAVE GREAT PASSION FOR
WHAT THEY DO.
WHEN EVERYONE DOES THEIR
PASSI
PASSION, WE ARRIVE AT
COMPASSION AND WE THANK YOU.
WE KNOW THAT YOU'RE MOST AWARE
OF THEIR NEEDS.
THEY, TOO, BECOME TIRED AND
SOMETIMES CLOSE TO BURNING O
OUT, HOW MUCH WE NEED ONE
ANOTHER.
WHEN YOU CALL JEREMIAH OR AMOS
OR BARUK AND ALL OF YOUR
PRECIOUS APOSTLES AND
PROPHETS, THEY HEDGED AT
FIRST, BUT EACH TIME IN TURN
THEY GAVE THEIR YES AND THEY
FOLLOWED YOU, KNOWING THAT YOU
WERE ALWAYS AMONG THEM, ALWAYS
SUPPORTING THEM.
THEY WERE CONDUITS FOR YOUR
EYES AND YOUR EARS AND YOUR
VOICE AND YOUR HANDS.
THEY WERE THE CLAY KNOWING
THAT YOU ALWAYS WERE THE
POTTER AND THEY WERE RESILIENT
IN YOUR HANDS.
WHEN JESUS FELT THE NEED TO
GET AWAY FOR SOME RESPITE
HIMSELF, HE WENT TO THE
MOUNTAINS OR INTO THE
WILDERNESS OR OUT TO THE
SEASHORE.
AND THE GREAT NUMBERS OF
PEOPLE IN NEED ALWAYS
FOLLOWED.
TIRED AND DRAINED, AS HE WAS,
HE LOOKED ON THEM WITH
COMPASSI
COMPASSION.
ANOINT ALL YOUR PEOPLE, LORD,
ALL OF THOSE WHO MINISTER TO
YOU AS THEY MINISTER TO ONE
ANOTHER AND ESPECIALLY THIS
WEEK AS THEY MINISTER TO THE
BODY, MIND AND SPIRIT, TO THE
WHOLE COMMUNITY OF SANDY HOOK
IN NEWTOWN, A MODEL FOR THE
NATION, A MODEL FOR THE WORLD.
AND WE THANK YOU FOR THE WORLD
SUPPO
SUPPORT, CALLING, E-MAILING,
TEXTING THEIR LOVE AND THEIR
COMMITMENT TO BE ONE WITH US.
USE THEM, LORD.
TAKE THE PASSION THAT EACH ONE
HAS AND TRANSFORM IT TOTALLY,
COMPLETELY, INTO YOUR SPIRIT
OF COMPASSION.
AND WE ASK THIS ALL, AMEN,
AMEN.
>>  A COMMUNITY OF DIFFERENT
FAVORITES, GRIEVING TOGETHER
IN THIS INTERFAITH VIGIL.
NEXT, JACK TANNER, MINISTER OF
NEWTOWN CHRISTIAN CHURCH
READING SCRIPTURE, ROMANS 8,
THEN WE'LL HEAR FROM A LOCAL
GOVERNMENT OFFICIAL, FIRST
SELECT WOMAN PATRICIA LODRA,
CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR DAN
MALLOY WILL THEN INTRODUCE
PRESIDENT OBAMA FOR HIS
REMARKS TO THIS CROWD.
AGAIN, YOU'RE LOOKING LIVE AT
NEWTOWN, HIGH SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT AND THIS
SCHOOL TRAGEDY THAT THEY'RE
DEALING WITH AFTER FRIDAY'S
SHOOTING.
NEWTOWN IS A PLACE THAT LOVES
CHILDREN ABOVE ALL.
FAMILIES MOVE TO NEWTOWN
BECAUSE WE ARE A CARING AND
LOVING COMMUNITY.
WE ARE ALSO A PLACE THAT HAS
GREAT PRIDE IN OUR SCHOOLS,
PRIDE THAT PROPELS THE
STUDENTS IN THOSE SCHOOLS WITH
THEIR OUTSTANDING TEACHERS AND
ADMINISTRATORS THROUGH HIGH
ACHIEVEMENT AND GREAT PERSONAL
WORTH.
THE HORROR THAT WAS VISITED
UPON OUR SANDY HOOK SCHOOL WAS
NOT DESERVED.
IT IS THE ANGRY AND DESPERATE
ACT OF A CONFUSED YOUNG MAN.
THERE IS NO BLAME TO BE LAID
ON US, BUT THERE IS A GREAT
BURDEN AND A GREAT CHALLENGE
THAT WE EMERGE WHOLE, THAT
THESE FAMILIES DEVASTATED BY
UNSPEAKABLE HARM KNOW AND
TRUST THAT WE LOVE THEM AND
WILL DO EVERYTHING WE CAN TO
HELP THEM HEAL.
I KNOW THAT NEWTOWN WILL
PREVAIL THAT WE WILL NOT FALL
TO ACTS OF VIOLENCE.
IT IS A DEFINING MOMENT FOR
OUR TOWN, BUT IT DOES NOT
DEFINE US.
WE ARE NEWTOWN, A SPECIAL AND
CARING PLACE.
WE ARE DEFINED BY ACTS OF
COURAGE, BY ACTS OF LOVE AND
BY OUR CONTINUING COMMITMENT
AND LOVE FOR OUR CHILDREN AND
FAMILIES.
IT IS MY PLEASURE, LADIES AND
GENTLEMEN, TO PRESENT TO YOU
GOVERNOR DAN MALLOY.
[APPLAUS
[APPLAUSE]
>>  PAT, THANK YOU FOR ALL OF
THE GREAT WORK THAT YOU HAVE
DONE FOR THIS COMMUNITY IN THE
LAST THREE DAYS, TO THE POLICE
CHIEF AND TO THE
SUPERINTENDENT OF SCHOOLS,
THANK YOU FOR YOUR GREAT
SERVICE AS WELL, TO ALL OF THE
FIRST RESPONDERS, THANK YOU.
WHEN I CAME IN TO THE HALL,
ONE OF THE FIRST SONGS TO BE
PLAYED ON THE PIANO WAS
"AMAZING WHICH IS
FITTING FOR ANY NUMBER OF
REASONS.
IT'S BECOME AN ANTHEM FOR
FIRST RESPONDERS.
IT HAS GREAT WORDS.
IT ALSO SPEAKS OF THE POWER OF
FAITH.
AMAZING GRACE WAS WRITTEN BY A
FORMER SEA CAPTAIN ENGAGED IN
THE--
>> WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A BRIEF
PAUSE AS WE LISTEN TO THE
CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR DAN
MALLOY TO BRING INTO THE FULL
FOX BROADCAST NETWORK.
WHEN WE ARE CALLED UPON, DARE
I SAY REQUIRED--
♪
>>  GOOD EVENING FROM
WASHINGTON, I'M BRET BAIER,
WE'RE JUST MINUTES AWAY FROM
PRESIDENT OBAMA SPEAKING IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT AS THE
NATION JOINS THAT COMMUNITY IN
MOURNING AFTER THE KILLING OF
26 PEOPLE INSIDE SANDY HOOK,
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, 20 OF THEM
CHILDREN, AGES SIX AND SEVEN
YEARS OLD.
SPEAKING NOW, CONNECTICUT
GOVERNOR DAN MALLOY, WHO WILL
INTRODUCE PRESIDENT OBAMA.
LET'S LISTEN IN.
>> TO SURVIVE THAT WHICH HAS
BEFALLEN THIS COMMUNITY, THESE
FAMILIES, THESE SPOUSES.
THAT WHICH HAS HAPPENED AND IS
UNIMAGINABLE AND UNTHINKABLE
AND WAS NEVER, WE THOUGHT,
INTENDED TO BE VISITED UPON US
HERE IN CONNECTICUT OR IN
NEWTOWN, OR IN SANDY HOOK.
I CHOOSE TO THINK ABOUT THE
FACT THAT IN THE COMING DAYS
WE WILL OFFICIALLY ENTER
WINTER.
AND THAT IS ALWAYS TO BE
FOLLOWED BY THE SPRING.
LET ME ASSURE YOU THAT IN
WINTER EACH TIME I SEE THE
BEGINNING OF A SNOWFALL, I
WILL BE THINKING OF THOSE 27
SOULS LOST JUST A FEW DAYS
AGO.
EACH TIME THE DAY GETS A
LITTLE LONGER, I WILL THINK
AND DREAM OF THE LIVES THAT
MIGHT HAVE BEEN AND THE LIVES
THAT WERE SO FULL OF GRACE.
AND WHEN THE FLOWERS START TO
COME OUT OF THE GROUND AND
WHEN THEY RISE UP, I WILL KNOW
THAT WE ARE IN TOUCH WITH
THOSE THAT WE'VE LOST IN THE
LAST FEW DAYS.
WE WILL GO ON.
WE WILL FIND STRENGTH.
FAITH IS A GIFT, AS IS OUR
ABILITY TO SUPPORT ONE ANOTHER
IN OUR GREATER COMMUNITY.
TO ALL OF YOU, I EXTEND MY
MOST PROFOUND CONDOLENCES ON
BEHALF OF ALL OF YOUR FELLOW
CITIZENS FOR WHAT YOU HAVE
SEEN, WHAT YOU HAVE WITNESSED
AND WHAT YOU HAVE PERSONALLY
EXPERIENCED.
WE WILL MOVE ON.
WE WILL NEVER FORGET.
WE WILL IN MANY WAYS BE MADE
STRONGER FOR WHAT HAS
TRANSPIRED.
AND WE WILL GET BETTER.
WE ARE BLESSED TODAY TO HAVE
WITH US THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES, WHO UPON BEING
WITH PAT AND I JUST A LITTLE
WHILE AGO, SAID THAT THE MOST
DIFFICULT DAY OF HIS
PRESIDENCY WAS FRIDAY WHEN HE
HEARD THE NEWS OF THAT WHICH
HAD BEFALLEN THIS COMMUNITY.
I ASSURED HIM THAT
CONNECTICUT, NEWTOWN, AND
SANDY HOOK ARE STRONG AND I
WELCOMED HIM ON YOUR BEHALF TO
OUR COMMUNITY.
I NOW INTRODUCE THE PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED STATES.
[APPLAUSE]
>>  THANK YOU.
THANK YOU, GOVERNOR.
TO ALL THE FAMILIES, FIRST
RESPONDERS, THE COMMUNITY OF
NEWTOWN, CLERGY, GUESTS,
SCRIPTURE TELLS US DO NOT LOSE
HEA
HEART.
THOUGH OUTWARDLY, WE ARE
WASTING AWAY INWARDLY WE ARE
BEING RENEWED DAY BY DAY.
FOR LIGHT MOMENTARY TROUBLES
ARE ACHIEVING ETERNAL GLORY
THAT FAR OUTWEIGHS THEM ALL
AND WE FIX OUR EYES NOT ON
WHAT IS SEEN, BUT WHAT IS
UNSEEN.
WHAT IS SEEN IS TEMPORARY, BUT
WHAT IS UNSEEN IS ETERNAL.
FOR WE KNOW THAT IF THE
EARTHLY TENT WE LIVE IN IS
DESTROYED, WE HAVE A BUILDING
FROM GOD.
AN ETERNAL HOUSE IN HEAVEN,
NOT BUILT BY HUMAN HANDS.
WE GATHER HERE IN MEMORY OF 20
BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN AND SIX
REMARKABLE ADULTS.
THEY LOST THEIR LIVES IN A
SCHOOL THAT COULD HAVE BEEN
ANY SCHOOL.
IN A QUIET TOWN FULL OF GOOD
AND DECENT PEOPLE, THAT COULD
BE ANY TOWN IN AMERICA.
HERE IN NEWTOWN, I COME TO
OFFER THE LOVE AND PRAYERS OF
A NATION.
I AM VERY MINDFUL THAT MERE
WORDS CANNOT MATCH THE DEPTHS
OF YOUR SORROW, NOR CAN THEY
HEAL YOUR WOUNDED HEARTS.
I CAN ONLY HOPE IT HELPS FOR
YOU TO KNOW THAT YOU'RE NOT
ALONE IN YOUR GRIEF.
THAT OUR WORLD, TOO, HAS BEEN
TORN APART.
THAT ALL ACROSS THIS LAND OF
OURS WE HAVE WEPT WITH YOU.
WE'VE PULLED OUR CHILDREN
TIGHT.
AND YOU MUST KNOW THAT
WHATEVER MEASURE OF COMFORT WE
CAN PROVIDE, WE WILL PROVIDE
IT.
WHATEVER PORTION OF SADNESS
THAT WE CAN SHARE WITH YOU TO
EASE THIS HEAVY LOAD, WE WILL
GLADLY BEAR IT.
NEWTOWN, YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
AS THESE DIFFICULT DAYS HAVE
UNFOLDED, WE'VE ALYOU'VE ALSO ID
US, STORIES OF STRENGTH AND
RESOLVE AND SACRIFICE.
WE KNOW THAT WHEN DANGER
ARRIVED IN THE HALLS OF SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY, THE SCHOOL
STAFF DID NOT FLINCH, THEY DID
NOT HESITATE.
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, MARY
SHERLACH, VICKY SOTO, LAUREN
RUSSEAU, RACHEL DEVINO AND ANN
MARIE MURPHY, THEY ALL
RESPONDED AS WE ALL HOPED WE
MIGHT RESPOND IN SUCH
TERRIFYING CIRCUMSTANCES, WITH
COURAGE AND WITH LOVE, GIVING
THEIR LIVES TO PROTECT THE
CHILDREN IN THEIR CARE.
WE KNOW THAT THERE WERE OTHER
TEACHERS WHO BARRICADED THEM
SELVES INSIDE CLASSROOMS AND
KEPT STEADY THROUGH IT ALL.
AND REASSURED THEIR STUDENTS
BY SAYING, WAIT FOR THE GOOD
GUYS, THEY'RE COMING.
SHOW ME YOUR SMILE.
AND WE KNOW THAT GOOD GUYS
CAME, THE FIRST RESPONDERS WHO
RACED TO THE SCENE, HELPING
THOSE IN HARM'S WAY TO SAFETY
AND COMFORT THOSE IN NEED,
HOLDING AT BAY THEIR OWN SHOCK
AND THEIR OWN TRAUMA BECAUSE
THEY HAD A JOB TO DO.
AND OTHERS NEEDED THEM MORE.
AND THEN, THERE WERE THE
SCENES OF THE SCHOOL CHILDREN,
HELPING ONE ANOTHER, HOLDING
EACH OTHER, DUTIFULLY
FOLLOWING INSTRUCTIONS THE WAY
THAT YOUNG CHILDREN SOMETIMES
DO.
ONE CHILD EVEN TRIED TO
ENCOURAGE A GROWNUP BY SAYING,
I KNOW KARATE, SO, IT'S OKAY,
I'LL LEAD THE WAY OUT.
AS A COMMUNITY, YOU'VE
INSPIRED US, NEWTOWN.
IN THE FACE OF INDESCRIBABLE
VIOLENCE, IN THE FACE OF
UNCONSCIONABLE EVIL, YOU'VE
LOOKED OUT FOR EACH OTHER,
YOU'VE CARED FOR ONE ANOTHER
AND YOU'VE LOVED ONE ANOTHER.
THIS IS HOW NEWTOWN WILL BE
REMEMBER
REMEMBERED.
AND WITH TIME AND GOD'S GRACE,
THAT LOVE WILL SEE YOU
THROUGH.
BUT WE AS A NATION, WE ARE
LEFT WITH SOME HARD QUESTIONS.
YOU KNOW, SOMEONE ONCE
DESCRIBED THE JOY AND ANXIETY
OF PARENTHOOD AS THE
EQUIVALENT OF HAVING YOUR
HEART OUTSIDE OF YOUR BODY ALL
THE TIME.
WALKING AROUND.
WITH THEIR VERY FIRST CRY,
THIS MOST PRECIOUS, VITAL PART
OF OURSELVES, OUR CHILD, IS
SUDDENLY EXPOSED TO THE WORLD,
POSSIBLE MISHAPS OR MALICE.
AND EVERY PARENT KNOWS THERE'S
NOTHING WE WILL NOT DO TO
SHIELD OUR CHILDREN FROM HARM.
AND YET, WE ALSO KNOW THAT
WITH THAT CHILD'S VERY FIRST
STEP, AND EACH STEP AFTER
THAT, THEY'RE SEPARATING FROM
US.
THAT WE WON'T, THAT WE CAN'T
ALWAYS BE THERE FOR THEM.
THEY'LL SUFFER SICKNESS AND
SETBACKS AND BROKEN HEARTS,
AND DISAPPOINTMENTS.
AND WE LEARN THAT OUR MOST
IMPORTANT BE JOB IS TO GIVE
THEM WHAT THEY NEED TO BECOME
SELF-RELIANT AND CAPABLE AND
RESILIENT READY TO FACE THE
WORLD WITHOUT FEAR.
AND WE KNOW WE CAN'T DO THIS
BY OURSELVES.
IT COMES AS A SHOCK AT A
CERTAIN POINT WHEN YOU REALIZE
NO MATTER HOW MUCH YOU LOVE
THESE KIDS, YOU CAN'T DO IT BY
YOURSELF.
THAT THIS JOB OF KEEPING OUR
CHILDREN SAFE AND TEACHING
THEM WELL IS SOMETHING WE CAN
ONLY DO TOGETHER.
WITH THE HELP OF FRIENDS AND
NEIGHBORS, THE HELP OF A
COMMUNITY, AND THE HELP OF A
NATION.
AND IN THAT WAY, WE COME TO
REALIZE THAT WE BEAR A
RESPONSIBILITY FOR EVERY CHILD
BECAUSE WE'RE COUNTING ON
EVERYBODY ELSE TO HELP LOOK
AFTER OURS.
AND WE'RE ALL PARENTS.
THAT THEY'RE ALL OUR CHILDREN.
THIS IS OUR FIRST TASK, CARING
FOR OUR CHILDREN.
IT'S OUR FIRST JOB.
IF WE DON'T GET THAT RIGHT WE
DON'T GET ANYTHING RIGHT.
THAT'S HOW, AS A SOCIETY, WE
WILL BE JUDGED.
AND BY THAT MEASURE, CAN WE
TRULY SAY AS A NATION THAT
WE'RE MEETING OUR OBLIGATIONS.
CAN WE HONESTLY SAY THAT WE'RE
DOING ENOUGH TO KEEP OUR
CHILDR
CHILDREN, ALL OF THEM, SAFE
FROM HARM?
CAN WE CLAIM AS A NATION THAT
WE'RE ALTOGETHER THERE,
LETTING THEM KNOW THAT THEY'RE
LOVED AND TEACHING THEM TO
LOVE IN RETURN?
CAN WE SAY THAT WE'RE TRULY
DOING ENOUGH TO GIVE ALL THE
CHILDREN OF THIS COUNTRY THE
CHANCE THEY DESERVE TO LIVE
OUT THEIR LIVES IN HAPPINESS
AND WITH PURPOSE?
I'VE BEEN REFLECTING ON THIS
THE LAST FEW DAYS AND IF WE'RE
HONEST WITH OURSELVES, THE
ANSWER IS NO.
WE'RE NOT DOING ENOUGH.
AND WE WILL HAVE TO CHANGE.
SINCE I'VE BEEN PRESIDENT,
THIS IS THE FOURTH TIME WE
HAVE COME TOGETHER TO COMFORT
A GRIEVING COMMUNITY TORN
APART BY MASS SHOOTINGS.
FOURTH TIME WE'VE HUGGED
SURVIVORS, THE FOURTH TIME
WE'VE CONSOLED THE FAMILIES OF
VICTIMS.
AND IN BETWEEN THERE HAVE BEEN
AN ENDLESS SERIES OF DEADLY
SHOOTINGS ACROSS THE COUNTRY,
ALMOST DAILY REPORTS OF
VICTIMS, MANY OF THEM
CHILDREN.
IN SMALL TOWNS AND BIG CITIES
ACROSS AMERICA, VICTIMS WHO
MUCH OF THE TIME THEIR ONLY
FAULT WAS BEING IN THE WRONG
PLACE AT THE WRONG TIME.
WE CAN'T TOLERATE THIS
ANYMORE.
THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
AND TO END THEM, WE MUST
CHANGE.
WE WILL BE TOLD THAT THE
CAUSES OF SUCH VIOLENCE ARE
COMPLEX AND THAT IS TRUE.
NO SINGLE LAW, NO SET OF LAWS
CAN ELIMINATE EVIL FROM THE
WORLD OR PREVENT EVERY
SENSELESS ACT OF VIOLENCE IN
OUR SOCIETY, BUT THAT CAN'T BE
AN EXCUSE FOR INACTION.
SURELY, WE CAN DO BETTER THAN
THIS.
IF THERE'S EVEN ONE STEP WE
CAN TAKE TO SAVE ANOTHER CHILD
OR ANOTHER PARENT OR ANOTHER
TOWN FROM THE GRIEF THAT'S
VISITED TUCSON AND AURORA AND
OAK CREEK AND NEWTOWN, AND
COMMUNITIES FROM COLUMBINE TO
BLACKSBERG BEFORE THAT, SURELY
WE HAVE AN OBLIGATION TO TRY.
IN THE COMING WEEKS I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE
HOLDS TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW
CITIZENS FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT
TO MENTAL HEALTH
PROFESSIONALS, TO PARENTS AND
EDUCATORS, IN AN EFFORT AIMED
AT PREVENTING MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS BECAUSE WHAT CHOICE
DO WE HAVE?
WE CAN'T ACCEPT EVENTS LIKE
THIS AS ROUTINE.
ARE WE REALLY PREPARED TO SAY
THAT WE'RE POWERLESS IN THE
FACE OF SUCH CARNAGE?
THAT THE POLITICS ARE TOO HA
HARD?
ARE WE PREPARED TO SAY THAT
SUCH VIOLENCE VISITED ON OUR
CHILDREN YEAR AFTER YEAR AFTER
YEAR, SOMEHOW THE PRICE OF OUR
FREEDOM?
IN ALL THE WORLD'S RELIGIONS,
SO MANY OF THEM REPRESENTED
HERE TODAY, START WITH A
QUESTION.
WHY ARE WE HERE?
WHAT GIVES OUR LIFE MEANING?
WHAT GIVES OUR ACTS PURPOSE?
WE KNOW OUR TIME ON THIS EARTH
IS FLEETING.
WE KNOW THAT WE WILL EACH HAVE
OUR SHARE OF PLEASURE AND
PAIN, THAT EVEN AFTER WE
CHAN
CHASE AFTER SOME EARTHLY GOAL,
WHETHER IT'S WEALTH, POWER,
FAME OR SIMPLE COMFORT, WE
WILL IN SOME FASHION FALL
SHORT OF WHAT WE HAD HOPED.
WE KNOW THAT NO MATTER HOW
GOOD OUR INTENTIONS WE'LL ALL
STUMBL SOMETIMES IN SOME WAY.
WE'LL MAKE MISTAKES.
WE'LL EXPERIENCE HARDSHIPS.
AND EVEN WHEN WE'RE TRYING TO
DO THE RIGHT THING, WE KNOW
THAT MUCH OF OUR TIME WILL BE
SPENT GROPING THROUGH THE
DARKNESS, SO OFTEN UNABLE TO
DISCERN GOD'S HEAVENLY PLANS.
THERE'S ONLY ONE THING WE CAN
BE SURE OF AND THAT IS THE
LOVE THAT WE HAVE FOR OUR
CHILDREN, FOR OUR FAMILIES,
FOR EACH OTHER.
THE WARMTH OF A SMALL CHILD'S
EMBRACE, THAT IS TRUE.
THE MEMORIES WE HAVE OF THEM,
THE JOY THAT THEY BRING, THE
WONDER WE SEE THROUGH THEIR
EYES, THAT FIERCE AND
BOUNDLESS LOVE WE FEEL FOR
THEM, A LOVE THAT TAKES US OUT
OF OURSELVES AND BINDS US TO
SOMETHING LARGER, WE KNOW
THAT'S WHAT MATTERS.
WE KNOW WE'RE ALWAYS DOING
RIGHT WHEN WE'RE TAKING CARE
OF THEM.
WHEN WE'RE TEACHING THEM WELL.
WHEN WE'RE SHOWING ACTS OF
KINDNESS.
WE DON'T GO WRONG WHEN WE DO
THAT.
THAT'S WHAT WE CAN BE SURE
OF.
AND THAT'S WHAT YOU, THE
PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN, HAVE
REMINDED US.
AND THAT'S HOW YOU'VE INSPIRED
US.
YOU REMIND US WHAT MATTERS.
THAT'S WHAT SHOULD DRIVE US
FORWARD IN EVERYTHING WE DO.
FOR AS LONG AS GOD SEES FIT TO
KEEP US ON THIS EARTH.
LET THE LITTLE CHILDREN COME
TO ME, JESUS SAID, AND DO NOT
HINDER THEM, FOR SUCH BELONGS
THE KINGDOM OF HEAVEN.
CHARLOTTE, DANIEL, OLIVIA,
JOSEPHINE, ANNA, DYLAN,
MADELINE, KATHERINE, CHASE,
JESSE, JAMES, GRACE, E MCMILIE,
CAROLINE, NOAH, JESSICA,
BENJAMIN, ALISON, GOD HAS
CALLED THEM ALL HOME, FOR
THOSE OF US WHO REMAIN, LET US
FIND THE STRENGTH TO CARRY ON
AND MAKE OUR COUNTRY WORTH
THINK OF THEIR MEMORY.
MAY GOD BLESS AND KEEP THOSE
WE'VE LOST IN HIS HEAVENLY
PLACE.
MAY HE GRACE THOSE WE STILL
HAVE WITH HIS HOLY COMFORT AND
MAY HE BLESS AND WATCH OVER
THIS COMMUNITY AND THE UNITED
STATES OF AMERICA.
>> .
>> Bret: PRESIDENT OBAMA
SPEAKING JUST UNDER 18 MINUTES
IN THE ROLE OF CONSOLER IN
CHIEF, SAYING NEWTOWN, YOU ARE
NOT ALONE.
THE PRESIDENT MENTIONED
TEACHERS WHO DIDN'T MAKE IT
OUT OF SANDY HOOK SCHOOL, AND
JUST AS HE READ THE NAMES THE
SOUND OF WEEPING IN THE
AUDITORIUM.
THE PRESIDENT SAID DECISIONS
LIE AHEAD AND NOT DOING
ENOUGH, AND HE STEERED CLEAR
OF POLICY PRESCRIPTIONS, BUT
SAID WE NEED TO CHANGE.
TONIGHT HE FOCUSED ON HEALING,
HEALING NEWTOWN AND A NATION
SHOCKED BY AN UNTHINKABLE
CRIME.
I'M BRET BAIER IN WASHINGTON,
FOR THOSE OF YOU ON FOX
BROADCASTING, WE RETURN YOU TO
REGULARLY SCHEDULED
PROGRAMMING, CONTINUOUS
UPDATES ON FOXNEWS.COM AND ON
FOX NEWS CHANNEL OUR COVERAGE
CONTINUES RIGHT NOW.
>>  THE COVERAGE CONTINUES AND
WE LISTEN TO THE PRAYERS AND
THE INTERFAITH VIGIL.
>> THERE'S NOT JUST A COUNTRY
STANDING BEHIND US, BUT
THERE'S A WORLD STANDING
BEHIND US, THE WORD I KNOW AS
DIFFICULT AS THEY WERE TO HEAR
FROM SOME FOR CONSOLATION TO
US ALL.
I WANT TO THANK THE GOVERNORS
AND STATE OFFICIALS WHO HAVE
BEEN BY OUR SIDE SINCE DAY
ONE, THEY'VE BEEN A REMARKABLE
REMINDER TO US OF THEIR
HUMANITY AND THEIR CARE FOR
US, BUT MOST OF ALL, I WANT TO
THANK A INCREDIBN INCREDIBLE WO
LED US THROUGH THE MOST DARK
PERIODS OF OUR LIVES
(APPLAUSE)
WHEN THE STORMS OF THE PAST
YEARS, I THOUGHT THOSE WERE
THE HARDEST PAST LIVES, AND
WHEN I SAW HER IN FRONT OF
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL, THOSE WERE
THE DARKEST DAYS.
PAT THANK YOU FOR BEING
LEADERS TO US THROUGH THESE
DIFFICULT TIMES AND NOW THIS
FINAL PART OF OUR PRAYER IS
FOR US, THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN.
THESE ARE THE WORDS OF THE
APOSTLE PAUL AS HE WRITES TO
THE CHURCH AT ROME.
WHAT THEN SHALL WE SAY IN
RESPONSE TO THIS?
IF GOD IS FOR US, WHO CAN BE
AGAINST US?
HE WHO DID NOT SPARE HIS OWN
SON, BUT GAVE UP FOR ALL OF
US.
EMBRACES US AND GIVE US ALL
THINGS.
WHOM WILL BRING CHARGES
AGAINST THOSE WHOM GOD HAS
CHOSEN?
IT IS GOD WHO JUSTIFIES, WHO
IS HE WHO CONDEMNS.
CHRIST JESUS WHO DIED AND
AFTER THAT RAISED TO LIFE IS
AT THE RIGHT-HAND OF GOD AND
INTERCEDING FOR US.
WHO SHALL SEPARATE US FROM THE
LOVE OF CHRIST, SHALL TROUBLE
OR HARDSHIP OR PURPERSECUTION O
NAKEDNESS, AND AS WRITTEN,
YOUR FAITH ALL DAY LONG WE'RE
CONSIDERED TO BE SLEEP TO BE
SLAUGHTERED.
NO, IN ALL OF THESE THINGS
WE'RE MORE THAN CONGRESS FOR
THOSE WHO LOVED US FOR I AM
CONVINCED THAT NEITHER DEATH
NOR LIFE.
ANGELS NOR DEMONS, THE PRESENT
NOR THE FUTURE OR HEIGHT OR
DEATH ANYTHING ELSE, IN ALL
CREATION WILL BE ABLE TO
SEPARATE US FROM THE LOVE OF
GOD THAT IS IN CHRIST JESUS
OUR LORD.
[APPLAUS
[APPLAUSE].
SO WE STAND NOW IN PRAYER FOR
OURSELVES.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN, BUT OUR
SPIRITS ARE STRENGTHENED BY
THE POWER OF GOD'S GOODNESS
AND HIS EVER CREATING LOVE AND
BY THE GENEROUS HEARTS OF A
COMMUNITY WHO TRULY CARES AND
WE HAVE SHOWN TO THE WORLD OUR