PERIODS.
NSAIDS, INCLUDING CELEBREX,
INCREASE THE CHANCE OF SERIOUS
SKIN OR ALLERGIC REACTIONS
OR STOMACH A INTESTINE
PROBLEMS,
SUCH AS BLEEDING AND CERS,
WHICH CAN OCCUR WITHOUT WARNING
AND MAY CAUSE DEATH.
PATIENTS ALSO TAKING ASPIRIN
AND THE ELDEY
ARE AT INCRSED RISK FOR
STOCH BLEEDING AND ULCERS.
DO NOT TAKE CELEBREX IF YOU'VE
HAD AN ASTHMA ATTACK, HIVES,
OR OTHER ALLERGIES TO ASPIRIN,
NSAIDS OR SULFONAMIDES.
GET HELP RIGHTWAY IF YOU HAVE
SWELNG OF THE FACE OR THROAT,
OR TROUBLE BREATHING.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
YOUR MEDICAL HISTORY
AND FIND AN ARTHRITIS TREATMENT
FOR YOU.
VISIT CELEBREX.COM AND ASK
YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT CELEBREX.
FOR A BODY IN MOTION.
>> Chris: CHILLING NEW
DEVELOPMENTS INTO THE
INVESTIGATION AND ONE OF
DEADLIEST SHOOTINGS IN U.S.
HISTORY.
THE DEATH TOLL STANDS AT 28.
27 OF THE VICTIMS.
ER ON THE GUNMAN.
WELCOME TO BRAND-NEW HOUR.
I'M RICK FOLBAUM.
>> Jamie: I'M JAMIE COLBY.
WE'RE LEARNING NEW INFORMATION
ABOUT THE GUNMAN.
ADAM A LANZA WHO IS THE SUSPECT
IN THIS CASE DID FORCE HIS WAY
INTO SCHOOL IN CONTRARY TO
EARLIER REPORTS.
THEY ARE NOT ABLE TO FIND A
CONNECTION BETWEEN THE MOTHER
AND SCHOOL.
IT HAD BEEN REPORTED SHE WAS A
TEACHER OR SUBSTITUTE TEACHER
BUT NOT TRUE.
THE COMMUNITY THERE HAS SUFFERED
UNSPEAKABLE PAIN.
THE RESIDENTS OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT ARE OVERCOME WITH
GRIEF AND WONDERING IF THEIR
LIFE WILL EVER RETURN TO NORMAL.
>> IT'S UNBELIEVABLY TERRIBLE.
WE HAVE OUR KIDS THIS MORNING
AND OUR CLOSEST FRIENDS HAVE
THEIR KIDS THIS MORNING.
IT'S THE PEOPLE THAT DON'T.
>> WE KNOW A FRIEND THAT KNOWS
THE PRINCIPAL AND ALL THE LITTLE
KIDS.
IT DOESN'T FEEL LIKE IT
HAPPENED.
>> YOU DON'T SEE THEM -- LIKE
9/11, YOU'LL SEE THEM COME
TOGETHER.
THEY WILL PULL TOGETHER.
MARK MY WORD.
IT'S A GOOD TOWN.
>> Rick: MIKE IS LIVE IN NEWTOWN
WE HEARD FROM THAT GENTLEMAN.
ITS GOOD TOWN.
HOW ARE THE PEOPLE DOING TODAY?
>> THEY ARE TRYING TO GET THEIR
ARMS ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED AS THE
INNOCENT OF THIS TOWN HAS BEEN
SHATTERED.
ST. ROSE A CATHOLIC CHURCH HAS
BEEN A FOCAL POINT FOR THE
GRIEVING.
THEY GO INTO THE SANCTUARY TO
PRAY.
THE PEOPLE IN THE TOWN HAVE
BEGUN RIBBONS OF BLUE AND GOLD
ON THEM AND SADLY FAMILIAR THE
MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS HAVE BEEN
POPPING UP ALL OVER TOWN, AS
THIS TOWN IS SMALL ENOUGH THAT
JUST ABOUT EVERYONE HERE KNOWS
SOMEONE WHO WAS LOST IN THE
TRAGEDY.
>> A NEIGHBOR DOWN THE STREET
LOST A LITTLE BOY, A
SIX-YEAR-OLD.
A GOOD FRIEND OF MINE FOUND OUT
HIS SON WAS LOST ON BASEBALL
TEAM.
I DON'T GET IT.
>> Reporter: PARENTS SAY THE
FOCUS IS NOW ON THE KIDS TRYING
TO EXPLAIN THIS TO THEM IN SUCH
A WAY THEY CAN COME OUT OF THIS
STRONGER.
IT'S VERY DIFFICULT TASK WHEN
THE PARENTS THEMSELVES CAN'T
MAKE SENSE OF WHAT HAPPENED
HERE.
>> Rick: THERE ARE PROFESSIONALS
THAT SPECIALIZE IN THIS AND
GRIEF COUNSELORS.
TALK ABOUT THE SERVICES THAT ARE
BEING MADE AVAILABLE TO THERE.
>> AS MUCH AS YOU HAVE THE
COMMUNITY COMING TOGETHER.
YOU DO HAVE GRIEF COUNSELING AND
THE GRIEF COUNSELING IS DIVIDED
INTO TWO DIFFERENT SECTIONS.
ONE FOR ADULTS AND ONE FOR THE
CHILDREN.
WITH THE CHILDREN THEY HAVE
THERAPY DOGS TO HELP THE KIDS
GET COMFORTABLE.
THEY HAVE PEOPLE FROM ALL OVER
THE NATION AND SENT THINGS LIKE
TOYS, STUFFED ANIMALS SO THE
KIDS CAN GET COMFORTABLE SO THEY
CAN TALK ABOUT WHAT THEY SAW AND
EXPERIENCED AND TRY TO GET THEIR
ARMS AROUND THIS TERRIBLE
SITUATION HERE.
>> Rick: MIKE TOBIN LIVE, THANKS
SO MUCH.
>> Jamie: THE CHAOS AND HORROR
OF THE UNFOLDING TRAGEDY
CAPTURED IN POLICE DISPATCH
CASE.
>> CALLER IS INDICATING SHE
THINKS THERE IS SOMEBODYOTING I.
>> THE FRONT GLASS -- I'M NOT
SURE WHY...
>> Jamie: THE INVESTIGATION INTO
THIS TRAGEDY IS IN THE EARLIEST
STAGES BUT ACCORDING TO THE
CALLS IT MAY HAVE TAKEN A FEW
MINUTES FOR A GOWNS KILL SO MANY
AT THAT SCHOOL.
>> Rick: THREE MINUTES.
GRIEF COUNSELORS ARE ON HAND AND
OFFERING SUPPORT TO VICTIMS'
FAMILIES.
A SPOKESMAN FOR THE POLICE
GIVING REACTION TO THE
SHOOTINGS.
>> ITS TERRIBLE TRAGEDY.
IT'S WORK THAT WE NEED TO DO AND
GET DONE.
WE ARE PROVIDING OUR PEOPLE WITH
SUPPORT, WITH COUNSELING AS WE
CAN.
CERTAINLY THIS IS A HUGE, HUGE
TRAGEDY FOR EVERYBODY.
IT BREAKS OUR HEARTS THAT THE
FAMILIES ARE GOING THROUGH WHAT
THEY ARE GOING THROUGH.
IT'S JUST AN ATROCIOUS TRAGEDY.
>> Jamie: HERE IS ONE OF THE
STORIES TO COME OUT.
HEARTBROKEN FATHER SPEAKING OUT
ABOUT SIX-YEAR-OLD SON KILLED
YESTERDAY IN FIRST GRADE
CLASSROOM.
50-YEAR-OLD NEIL DROPPED HIS
LITTLE BOY OFF AT SCHOOL.
HE TOLD THE "NEW YORK POST", HE
WENT INTO THE SCHOOL HAPPILY.
HE PLANNED TO RETURN LATER IN
THE AFTERNOON AND HAD PLANS TO
MAKE GINGERBREAD HOUSES THAT
DAY.
WATCHING HIS SON RUNNING INTO
THE BUILDING WAS THE LAST TIME
HE EVER SAW HIM.
THE SON LOVED ANIMALS, MATH AND
WAS VERY HAPPY LITTLE BOY.
WE'RE ALSO HEARING STORIES OF
BRAVERY.
SEVERAL STAFF MEMBERS AT THE
SCHOOL REPORTEDLY SACRIFICED
THEMSELVES TO SAVE THEIR LIVES
AS MANY STUDENTS AS THEY COULD.
INCLUDING IN THAT THE AMAZING
STORY OF PRINCIPAL DAWN HUXBURN.
COLLEAGUES SAY SHE NEVER
HESITATED.
SHE RAN STRAIGHT FOR THE GUNMAN
AND THAT MOVE ENDED UP COSTING
HER LIFE.
HER FRIEND A LIBRARY CLERK SAYS
HER DEATH WILL BE DEVASTATING TO
THE COMMUNITY.
>> WE HAD A BOOK FAIR A FEW
WEEKS AGO.
SHE WAS READING FAIRY AND WENT
AROUND THE CLASSROOM AND SHE WAS
AN AMAZING WOMAN.
SHE WAS STRONG AND FUN.
THE KIDS LOVED HER.
SHE WAS REALLY WONDERFUL WOMAN.
IT'S A HUGE LOSS.
WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT HOW THE
SCHOOL AND LEADERSHIP SHE WAS
THE PERSON THAT MOST COULD HAVE
DONE THAT.
>> Jamie: CLEARLY SHE LOVED THAT
SCHOOL SO MUCH.
SHE IS ALSO THE PRINCIPAL THAT
BEEFED UP SECURITY IN THE
SCHOOL.
SHE LEAVES BEHIND A HUSBAND, TWO
DAUGHTERS AND THREE
STEP-CHILDREN.
HER ACTS TRULY HEROIC.
>> Rick: I LONG WITH THE
PRINCIPAL WE KNOW OF TWO OTHER
STAFF MEMBERS WHO DIED.
VICTORIA SOTO, A YOUNG FIRST
GRADE TEACHER HID CHILDREN IN
CLOSETS AND CONFRONTED THE
GUNMAN HERSELF TELLING HER THERE
WERE NO KIDS IN THE CLASSROOM.
56-YEAR-OLD MARY SHERLOCK.
SHE RAN INTO THE HALLWAY ALONG
WITH THE PRINCIPAL TO CONFRONTED
THE SHOOTER.
IT'S BELIEVED THEY WERE THE
GUNMAN'S FIRST TWO VICTIMS.
>>> AS WE CONTINUE TO LEARN MORE
ABOUT THE DEADLY SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
WE WANT TO TAKE BACK A LOOK AT
YESTERDAY'S EVENT.
>> EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY
TODAY.
>> A CALL CAME INTO DISPATCH.
POLICE OFFICERS AND RESOURCES
FROM ALL OVER THE STATE RACED TO
THAT AREA AS THEY CONVERGED ON
THE SCHOOL.
[ SIREN ]
>> CHILDREN OBVIOUSLY WERE VERY
SHAKEN AND CRYING IN THE CLOSET.
WHEN THEY WERE LEAVING, THEY
WERE TOLD TO HOLD HANDS AND TOLD
CLOSE THEIR EYES.
>> THEY HAVE THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM, BIRTHDAYS,
GRADUATIONS, WEDDINGS.
>> MY GYM TEACHER WAS SAID TO
GET AGAINST THE WALL AND
EVERYBODY STARTED PANICKING.
>> IT DOESN'T EVEN SEEM REAL.
IT SEEMS IMPOSSIBLE.
>> I KEPT HEARING BOOMING
NOISES.
[ SIREN ]
>> I HEARD ALL THIS STUFF GOING
ON.
>> THE KIDS WERE TERRIFIED.
THEY WERE TERRIFIED.
THIS HAD JUST WITNESSED
SOMETHING AND THEY WERE
TERRIFIED.
>> IT'S THE MOST FRIGHTENING
THING I'VE EVER BEEN THROUGH.
>> MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF
THE VICTIMS AND HEAL THE
BROKENHEARTED AND BIND UP THEIR
WOUNDS.
>> U.S. FLAG FLYING HALF-STAFF
ACROSS THE COUNTRY AS WE TAKE A
LOOK AT LIVE PICTURES.
PRESIDENT OBAMA ORDERING FLAG TO
BE LOWERED THROUGH NEXT TUESDAY.
>> Jamie: THERE IS A LOT MORE TO
TALK ABOUT.
WE'RE GOING DISCUSS SCHOOL
SAFETY.
SHOULD IT BE IMPROVED?
COULD IT HAVE PREVENTED THIS
TRAGEDY, STRAIGHT AHEAD.
THE Capital One
Cash Rewards Card
GIVES YOU 1% CASH BACK
ON ALL PURCHASES,
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS.
AND EVERYONE...BUT HER
LIKES 50% MORE CASH.
BUT I'M UPPING MY GAME.
DO YOU WANT A CANDY CANE?
YES!
DO YOU WANT THE PUPPY?
DO YOU WANT A TRICYCLE?
YES!
DO YOU WANT
50 PERCENT MORE CASH?
NO!
♪
FESTIVE.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE Capital One
Cash Rewards Card
GIVES YOU
1% CASH BACK
ON EVERY
PURCHASE
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS
ON THE CASH YOU EARN.
IT'S THE CARD FOR PEOPLE
WHO LIKE MORE CASH.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
>> Rick: FOX NEWS ALERT.
NEWS FROM CONNECTICUT WE'RE
LEARNING THAT HILLARY CLINTON IS
RECOVERING FROM A CONCUSSION
AFTER SHE FAINTED EARLIER THIS
WEEK.
RIGHT NOW THE SECRETARY IS AT
HOME WE'RE TOLD BEING MONITORED
BY DOCTORS.
SHE HAS BEEN UNDER THE WEATHER
FIGHTING A NASTY STOMACH VIRUS
THAT CAUSED HER TO CANCEL AN
OVERSEAS TRIP.
JAMES ROSEN HAS MORE.
>> GREETINGS FROM WASHINGTON
WHERE SECRETARY OF STATE CLINTON
HAD CANCELLED AN OVERSEAS TRIP
THAT WAS TO TAKE HER TO NORTH
AFRICA AND MIDEAST.
CLINTON HAS BEEN SUFFERING WHAT
AIDES HAVE BEEN DESCRIBING AS A
VICIOUS STOMACH VIRUS.
CANCELLATION OF THE TRIP WAS
UNUSUAL FOR THE VIGOROUS 65
YEARS OLD THAT LOGGED MORE
FLIGHT MILES THAN ANY SECRETARY
OF STATE.
ASSISTANT SECRETARY OF STATE
SAID IN A STATEMENT IRONED TODD,
I QUOTE, WHILE SUFFERING FROM A
STOMACH VIRUS, SECRETARY CLINTON
BECAME DEHYDRATED AND FAINTED.
SHE HAS BEEN RECOVERING AT HOME
AND WILL CONTINUE TO BE
MONITORED REGULARLY BY HER
DOCTORS.
AT THEIR RECOMMENDATION SHE WILL
CONTINUE TO WORK FROM HOME
STAYING IN REGULAR CONTACT WITH
OFFICIALS.
SHE IS LOOKING FORWARD BEING
BACK INTO THE OFFICE SOON.
EARLIER THIS WEEK REPORTERS
CAUTIONED DEPARTMENT SPOKESWOMAN
ABOUT THE HEADLINES AROUND THE
WORLD SHE WOULD CREATE WHEN SHE
FIRST MENTIONED THAT THE
SECRETARY WAS, QUOTE, REALLY
VERY ILL.
>> SHE HAS A VERY UNCOMFORTABLE
STOMACH VIRUS.
IN ANY OF YOU KNOW THAT IS NOT
COMFORTABLE.
>> IT IS NOT LIFE-THREATENING.
>> IT IS NOT.
IT IS NOT LIFE-THREATENING.
>> SHE HAS NOT BEEN WORKING.
SHE IS TRYING TO RECOVER.
>> Reporter: WITH THIS NEWS THAT
SECRETARY CLINTON BE TESTIFYING
NEXT WEEK ON CAPITOL HILL ABOUT
THE EVENTS IN BENGHAZI.
BACK TO YOU IN NEW YORK.
>> Rick: JUST IN REGARDING THE
TESTIMONY THAT WAS EXPECTED FROM
THE SECRETARY ON CAPITOL HILL,
WE'RE HEARING FROM THE
CHAIRWOMAN OF THE HOUSE FOREIGN
AFFAIRS COMMITTEE OF FLORIDA WHO
IS SAYING WHILE SHE CERTAINLY
SORRY THAT SECRETARY CLINTON IS
SICK, SHE STILL EXPECTS HER TO
TESTIFY IN PERSON IN FRONT OF
THE HOUSE COMMITTEE.
WE'LL KEEP FOLLOWING THIS STORY
AND BRING YOU MORE AS WE GET IT.
>> Jamie: THE TRAGEDY AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY IS SHINING A
LIGHT ON SCHOOL SAFETY.
THAT SCHOOL HAD REPORTEDLY
INSTALLED A NEW SECURITY SYSTEM
AND DID CONDUCT REGULAR LOCKDOWN
DRILLS.
DESPITE THE PRECAUTIONS, THE
GUNMAN STILL FOUND AND FORCED
HIS WAY IN ACCORDING TO
AUTHORITIES.
JOINING ME IS A FORMER DETECTIVE
AND TOM, IT'S TIME THAT WE CALL
YOU TO ASK YOU AS PARENTS AND
AMERICANS WE CAN DO TO KEEP OUR
KIDS SAFER.
COULD IT HAVE BEEN PREVENTED?
>> NO.
THERE ARE CERTAIN EVENTS THAT
HAPPEN IN THIS WORLD.
WE HAVE VERY SICK PEOPLE, EVIL
PEOPLE AROUND THIS WORLD WHO ARE
LOOKING TO DO HARM.
WE CAN'T PROTECT EVERYTHING.
YOU CAN'T PROTECT THE PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED STATES EVERY
MOMENT OF THE DAY.
SO WHAT TO WE DO LOOKING
FORWARD?
WE LOOK TOWARDS EACH EXPERIENCE
THAT HAPPENED.
FROM COLUMBINE WE KNOW THAT
POLICE WAITED TOO LONG.
NOW, THEY HAVE THE ACTIVE
SHOOTER PROGRAM WHERE POLICE
RESPOND IN A QUICK WAY AND GOES
IN TEAMS OF TWO TO STOP WHAT IS
HAPPENING.
IT HAPPENED AT A MALL IN
PORTLAND AND IT HAPPENED
YESTERDAY.
A SHOOTING TOOK THREE MINUTES.
>> Jamie: IT'S HARD FOR PEOPLE
TO FATHOM, ONE PERSON CAN WALK
IN WITH A NUMBER OF WEAPONS AND
SHOOT SO MANY PEOPLE TO DEATH IN
SUCH A SHORT PERIOD OF TIME.
HOW WELL-TRAINED WOULD THIS
SUSPECT, THIS SHOOTER HAVE TO
BE?
>> NOT THAT WELL-TRAINED.
YOU ARE SHOOTING SITTING DUCKS.
YOU ARE SHOOTING LITTLE KIDS IN
THE CLASSROOM.
HOW WELL DO YOU HAVE TO BE
TRAINED?
LET'S TALK ABOUT WHAT WENT RIGHT
YESTERDAY.
HE HAD TO FIGHT HIS WAY INTO THE
SCHOOL.
FOR A SMALL COMMUNITY, 25,000,
30,000 PEOPLE HAD SOPHISTICATED
SYSTEMS THAT WE KNOW IN SCHOOLS
OR IN INSTITUTIONS TODAY.
HE HAD TO FIRE HIS WAY IN.
AT THE POINT IN TIME HE GOT IN,
THERE WERE TEACHERS AND
CONVERSATION ON STUDIO "B" ABOUT
MISS MARTIN.
HOW ABOUT THE UNSUNG HEROS THAT
NESTLED THEIR KIDS AND LOCK DOWN
THE KIDS.
MOST SCHOOLS AROUND THIS COUNTRY
AND LEARNING INSTITUTIONS,
COLLEGES PRACTICE THESE DRILLS.
THERE IS THE ROBO CALLING WHERE
NOT ONLY YOU ARE ALERTING THE
OTHER TEACHERS BUT YOU ARE
ALERTING THE PARENTS AND LOCAL
OFFICIALS.
THEN THE POLICE RESPONDED IN
HUNDREDS WITHIN MINUTES.
>> Jamie: ALL OF THAT WENT
RIGHT.
LET ME ASK YOU ABOUT OTHER
SCHOOLS.
SCHOOLS THAT HAVE INSTALLED
METAL DETECTORS.
IS IT WORTH IT?
>> IF YOU FEEL YOU NEED A METAL
DETECTOR, IT IS ANOTHER WAY.
COULD THIS GUY HAVE FIRED WITH A
METAL DETECTOR.
>> THE ENTRANCE THAT HAS THE
METAL DETECTER.
>> IF SOMEONE LET'S HIM IN A
DIFFERENT WAY, RELATIVE TO THIS,
THERE IS GOING TO BE TRAGEDIES,
EVENTS THAT HAPPEN IN THIS
COUNTRY WE'RE NOT GOING TO BE
ABLE TO GET OUR HEADS AROUND.
>> Jamie: YOU CAN LOOK SOMEONE
IN THE EYE AND HAVE AN EVIL
DEED.
SHOULD WE, MANY PARENTS ARE
CALLING FOR TRAINED ARMED
PROFESSIONAL AT THE DOOR OF THE
SCHOOL.
SHOULD WE INVEST IN THAT IF WE
ARE ABLE?
>> IF YOU FEEL THE NEED, YES.
LOOK AT NEW YORK CITY.
NEW YORK CITY HAS WHOLE DIVISION
THAT PROTECTS OUR SCHOOLS, HAS
METAL DETECTORS, HAS A
COMMANDING OFFICER THAT PROTECTS
OUR SCHOOLS.
LOOKING FORWARD WE HAD A
PRINCIPAL YESTERDAY FROM ALL
REPORTS WHO RAN TOWARDS THIS MAN
AND TRIED TO WRESTLE HIM DOWN
AND TRIED TO STOP HIM.
SHE LOST HER LIFE.
THAT COULD HAVE VERY EASILY
HAPPENED TO AN ARMED OFFICER.
WE KNOW FROM OUR HISTORY THAT
ARMED PEOPLE ARE A DETERRENT BUT
WE HAVE TO LOOK WHAT WE ARE
GOING TO LEARN FROM THIS
INCIDENT TO MAKE OUR
INSTITUTIONS SAFER.
>> Jamie: DO YOU THINK TEACHERS
SHOULD BE ABLE TO BEAR ARMS?
>> I DON'T THINK IT WILL MAKE
THAT BIG OF A DIFFERENCE.
THE TEACHERS THAT NESTLED THE
KIDS IN THE CLASSROOM, AND
ACCESS CARD SYSTEMS IS WHAT IS
GOING TO PROTECT OUR SCHOOLS
BETTER.
>> Jamie: THANKS FOR HELPING US
TO KEEP OUR KIDS SAFE.
>> LET'S SAY A PRAYER.
>> Rick: THEY ARE HELPING THE
FAMILIES OF VICTIMS.
PETER JOHNSON, JR. SPOKE WITH
HAD HIM.
HE TALKED ABOUT A CONVERSATION
HE HAD WITH A LITTLE BOY WHO
LOST HIS SISTER.
>> YOU KNOW, I STARTED TALKING
WITH HIM.
HE SAID TO ME, I DON'T HAVE
ANYBODY TO PLAY WITH ANYMORE.
I HAVE LOST MY BEST FRIEND.
I SAID TO HIM, THAT GOD IS GOING
TO SEND YOU SOME WONDERFUL NEW
FRIENDS.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE AFRAID.
YOU ALWAYS HAVE YOUR SISTER IN
YOUR HEART.
I SAID TO HIM, SHE IS VERY SAFE
AND SHE IS WITH GOD.
WE TALKED ABOUT WHAT HEAVEN WAS
LIKE AND HE REALIZED SHE WAS
GOING TO BE HAPPY AND SAFE.
IT WAS SHORTLY AFTER THAT HE
BROKE DOWN INTO TEARS.
>> Rick: CAN'T EVEN IMAGINE.
HE HAS BEEN WORKING TIRELESSLY
GATHERING WITH PARENTS AT A
LOCAL FIREHOUSE ON FRIDAY
EXPERIENCING THE JOY OF THEM OF
THEM BEING REUNITED WITH THEIR
CHILDREN AND THEN RECEIVING
TERRIBLE NEWS THAT SOME ARE NOT
COMING BACK.
THERE IS A FREE WITH A CROSS IN
MEMORY OF EACH OF THE VICTIMS.
>> Rick: IT'S VERY --.
>> Jamie: IT'S VERY HARD TO
REPORT FOR ALL OF US.
STRAIGHT AHEAD WE'RE GOING TO
HAVE A LIVE UPDATE FROM THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING AND A FORMER
PROFILER WILL GIVE US INSIGHT
INTO A MASS MURDERER YOU CAN'T
CALL IT ANYTHING OTHER THAN THE
MASSES MURDERER.
INVESTIGATORS ARE STILL
SEARCHING FOR MOTIVE, WHY?
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Sharable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
CAMPBELL'S HAS 24 NEW SOUPS
THAT WILL MAKE IT DROP OVER,
AND OVER AGAIN.
♪
FROM JAMMIN' JERK CHICKEN,
TO CREAMY GOUDA BISQUE.
SEE WHAT'S NEW FROM CAMPBELL'S.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
>>.
>> Jamie: WE'RE WAITING FOR
ANOTHER NEWS CONFERENCE TO GET
UNDERWAY IN NEWTOWN SO WE CAN
LEARN NEW DETAILS ABOUT THIS
TRAGEDY, BUT IN THE MEANTIME, WE
HAVE LEARNED NEW DETAILS ABOUT
THE GUNMAN AND HIS FAMILY.
SOME OF THE EVENTS THAT MAY HAVE
LED UP TO YESTERDAY'S SHOOTING.
MOLLY IS JOINING US IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THIS IS ALL DEVELOPING BUT SOME
OF THE INFORMATION HAS CHANGED.
WHAT CAN YOU TELL US?
>> Reporter: ABSOLUTELY.
FIRST OFF WE HAVE SEEN SOME OF
THE STATE POLICE AND POLICE
OFFICERS MOVING INTO THE SCENE
HERE.
WE MAY BE HAVING THAT BRIEFING
SHORTLY.
THE INFORMATION THAT HAS CHANGED
MOST SIGNIFICANTLY, REPORTS FROM
FEDERAL AUTHORITIES THAT THE
PERSON THAT WAS SHOT BY HER SON
WAS NOT, MOTHER THAT WAS SHOT
DID NOT WORK AT THE SCHOOL.
INITIAL REPORTS THAT SHE WAS
TEACHER IN ONE OF CLASSROOMS
THAT HAD BEEN SHOT UP DURING THE
MASSACRE.
ANOTHER PIECE OF INFORMATION IS
THREE WEAPONS WERE FOUND INSIDE
OF THE BUILDING INSTEAD OF TWO.
INITIALLY BEEN A REPORT THE
THIRD WEAPON HAD BEEN FOUND IN
THE SHOOTER'S CAR.
NOW, WE ARE GETTING REPORTS
THERE WERE THREE WEAPONS FOUND
INSIDE THE SCHOOL AND OTHER GUNS
WERE FOUND BACK AT THE MOTHER'S
HOUSE.
THE GUNS INSIDE THE SCHOOL THAT
AUTHORITIES BELIEVE WERE USED
WERE REGISTERED TO THE SHOOTER'S
MOTHER, NANCY.
WHEN IT COMES TO THE SHOOTER
HIMSELF, FEDERAL AUTHORITIES ARE
SAYING HE IT IS BELIEVED HE
SUFFERED FROM ASPERINGER'S
SYNDROME.
AS INVESTIGATORS WERE BEGINNING
THIS INVESTIGATION, HAVE NOT
BEEN IN TOUCH WITH HIM FOR
YEARS.
THAT THE FAMILY WAS ESTRANGED
FROM ADAM, AT LEAST THE FATHER
AND BROTHER WERE ESTRANGED.
THOSE ARE THE LATEST DETAILS
THAT HAVE CHANGED MOST
SIGNIFICANTLY.
AS THE NEXT BRIEFING GETS
UNDERWAY WE'LL GET MORE.
>> Jamie: I APPRECIATE THAT.
LET'S LISTEN IN AS WE GET MORE
INFORMATION.
>> WE BEGIN THIS AFTERNOON.
I WOULD LIKE TO INTRODUCE YOU
THE FIRST SELECT WOMAN OF THE
NEWTOWN, PAT.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON EVERYONE.
I HAVE COMMENTS ON BEHALF OF THE
TOWN GOV FANS.
NEWTOWN HAS SUFFERED A
HORRENDOUS TRAGEDY.
A CALM THAT HAS BROKEN OUR
HEARTS.
OUR WOUND IS DEEP BECAUSE WE ARE
A CLOSE-KNIT COMMUNITY.
WE TRULY CARE FOR EACH OTHER.
WE ARE COMING TOGETHER WITH LOVE
AND SUPPORTED FOR THOSE FAMILIES
WHO HAVE SUFFERED THIS TERRIBLE
LOSS.
WE ARE A STRONG AND CARING
PLACE.
WE WILL PUT AROUND THOSE
FAMILIES AND AROUND EACH OTHER.
WE WILL FIND A WAY TO HEAL SO
ALL OF OUR RESIDENTS, YOUNG AND
OLD, WILL FIND PEACE.
I ASK THAT YOU HELP US IN THIS
PROCESS.
PLEASE TREAT OUR COMMUNITY WITH
KINDNESS.
PLEASE KNOW THAT WE HAVE
SUFFERED A TERRIBLE LOSS AND WE
NEED YOUR RESPECT ON THIS
HEALING JOURNEY.
I TURN TO YOU AS PARENTS, AS
SIBLINGS, AS CARING PEOPLE TO
KNOW THAT YOUR WORDS AND YOUR
ACTIONS CAN HELP US ON THIS
HEALING JOURNEY OR YOU CAN
HINDER US.
I WANT TO TAKE A MOMENT TO THANK
ALL THE SUPPORT WE HAVE RECEIVED
FROM THE GOVERNOR'S OFFICE, FROM
THE STATE POLICE, FROM MANY
CLINICIANS AND CLERGY, FROM THE
OUTREACH ACROSS THE NATION AND
ACROSS THE WORLD.
I THINK WE WERE ALL TOUCHED BY
THE MAGNITUDE OF THIS TRAGEDY.
I THANK YOU VERY MUCH TO
LISTENING TO MY MESSAGE.
I HOPE YOU TAKE MY COMMENTS TO
HEART.
THANK YOU.
MY NAME IS SPELLED, LLODRA,
PRONOUNCESED LO-DRA.
I'M THE FIRST SELECT MAN OF THIS
COMMUNITY.
FIRST NAME IS PATRICIA.
>> THE SECOND GENTLEMAN THAT HAS
BEEN WORKING VERY HARD IN THIS
PROCESS WITH THE IDENTIFICATION
AND EXAMINATION.
I WOULD LIKE TO INTRODUCE YOU
THE STATE OF CONNECTICUT MEDICAL
EXAMINER, DR. H.WAYNE CARVER?
>> FIRST OF ALL ON BEHALF OF MY
WIFE AND MY SONS AND BEHALF OF
MY OTHER FAMILY OUR PEOPLE WE
WISH TO EXTEND OUR DEEPEST
SYMPATHIES TO THE FAMILIES AND
EVERYONE ELSE WHO HAS BEEN SO
HURT BY THIS EVENT.
OUR THOUGHTS AND OUR PRAYERS ARE
WITH YOU.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER'S OFFICE
GOT HERE, CHIEF MEDICAL EXAMINER
GOT HERE A COUPLE HOURS AFTER
THE BUILDING WAS SECURED.
WE WERE THERE UNTIL
APPROXIMATELY 12:30 LAST NIGHT.
WE THANKED THE EMERGENCY
SERVICES THAT BUILT US A
TEMPORARY FACILITY IN THE
PARKING LOT.
WE TOOK IDENTIFICATION,
PHOTOGRAPHS AND DID PRELIMINARY
IDENTIFICATION ON ALL THE
VICTIMS AND HAD EVERYBODY
TRANSPORTED BACK TO FARMINGTON
BY ABOUT 1:00 IN THE MORNING.
OUR ENTIRE STAFF TURNED OUT,
STARTED THE POST MORE TELL
EXAMINATIONS.
WE COMPLETED THE CHILDREN BY
ABOUT 1:30.
I BELIEVE EVERYBODY EXCEPT THE
ASSAILANT AND HIS MOTHER WILL BE
FINISHED TONIGHT.
I'LL DO THOSE TOMORROW MORNING.
LIEUTENANT AND STAFF HAVE THE
NAMES AND DATES OF BIRTH.
THAT WILL BE DISTRIBUTED -- I
HOPE YOU HAVE ENOUGH COPIES.
EVERYBODY'S DEATH WAS CAUSED BY
GUNSHOT WOUNDS.
OBVIOUSLY THE MANNER OF DEATH ON
ALL THESE CASES IS HOMICIDE.
>> HOW MANY MEDICAL EXAMINERS
WORKED?
>> I HAVE FOUR DOCTORS.
I THINK ALL TEN OF MY
TECHNICIANS BOTH FULL TIMERS AND
PART TIMERS WERE THERE.
ONE STUDENT FROM THE UNIVERSITY.
THIS WAS HER FIRST DAY.
THE MAJORITY OF OUR
INVESTIGATIVE STAFF WAS WORKING
ON THIS AT SOME POINT WHETHER
THEY WERE WITH US LAST NIGHT OR
ON THE JOB TODAY.
I THINK A LOT OF OUR CLERICAL,
WHAT THEY CALL PROCESSING PEOPLE
WERE THERE.
THEY ARE UP ON THE SECOND FLOOR
BUT I DIDN'T GET THERE TODAY.
DID EVERYBODY HEAR THE QUESTION?
DEALING WITH WHAT I DEAL WITH
ALL THE TIME, IS THIS ONE OVER
THE TOP.
I HAVE BEEN AT THIS OVER A THIRD
OF THE CENTURY.
I MAY NOT BE AVERAGE BUT THIS
PROBABLY IS THE WORST I HAVE
SEEN OR THE WORST THAT I KNOW OF
ANY OF MY COLLEAGUES HAVING
SEEN.
THAT ALL THE MORE MAKES ME PROUD
AND GRATEFUL TO OUR STAFF WHO
HAVE BEHAVED MOST PROFESSIONALLY
AND STRONGLY.
I HOPE THEY AND I HOPE THE
PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN DON'T...
>> I COULDN'T ANSWER THAT BUT
ALL THE WOUNDS THAT I KNOW OF AT
THIS POINT WERE CAUSED BY THE
LONG WEAPON.
>> THE RIFLE, WHAT CALIBER?
>> THE QUESTION WAS WHAT CALIBER
WERE THESE BULLETS.
I PROBABLY KNOW ABOUT FIREARMS
THAN MOST PATHOLOGISTS BUT IF I
SAY IN IT COURT THEY YELL AT ME
AND DON'T MAKE ME ANSWER.
I WILL LET THE POLICE DEAL WITH
THAT FOR YOU.
>> HOW ABOUT THE NATURE OF THE
WOUNDS, CLOSE RANGE, WERE THE
CHILDREN WHY SHOT FROM ACROSS
THE WOUND?
>> I ONLY DID SEVEN OF THE
AUTOPSIES.
VICTIMS I HAD RANGED FROM THREE
TO 11 WOUNDS APIECE AND ONLY SAW
TWO OF THEM WITH CLOSE RANGE
SHOOTING.
THAT IS A SAMPLE.
I REALLY DON'T HAVE DETAILED
INFORMATION ON THE REST OF THE
INJURIES.
>> IT WAS A LONG RIFLE THAT WAS
USED?
>> YES.
>> I'M LUCKY I CAN TELL YOU HOW
MANY I FOUND.
I DON'T KNOW.
THERE WERE LOTS OF THEM.
OKAY.
THIS TYPE OF WEAPON IS THE
BULLETS ARE DESIGNED IN SUCH A
FASHION THAT THE ENERGY, THIS IS
VERY CLINICAL BUT THE ENERGY IS
DEPOSITED IN THE TISSUE SO THE
BULLETS ARE THERE.
IT'S ALWAYS A DIFFICULT QUESTION
AND OBVIOUSLY I DON'T HAVE -- I
DON'T HAVE DETAILED INFORMATION
ON ALL OF THEM.
THIS IS VERY DEVASTATING SET OF
INJURIES.
THE BEST OF MY ABILITY TO ANSWER
THAT QUESTION WHICH IS ALWAYS
LESS THAN PERFECT, IF SO NOT FOR
VERY LONG.
ALL THE ONES -- I BELIEVE SO,
YES.
WE DID NOT BRING THE BODIES AND
FAMILIES INTO CONTACT.
WE TOOK PICTURES OF THEM OF THE
FACIAL FEATURES.
IT'S EASIER ON THE FAMILIES WHEN
YOU DO THAT.
THERE IS A TIME AND PLACE IN THE
GRIEVING PROCESS.
BUT TO ACCOMPLISH THIS WE
THOUGHT IT WOULD BE BEST TO DO
IT THIS WAY.
YOU CAN CONTROL THE SITUATION
DEPENDING ON YOUR PHOTOGRAPHER.
I HAVE VERY GOOD PHOTOGRAPHERS.
NO, I DON'T.
>> HOW YOUNG WAS THE YOUNGEST
AND HOW OLD WAS THE OLDEST?
>> YOU ARE GOING TO HAVE LOOK AT
THE SPREADSHEET.
EVERYBODY I SAW, I BELIEVE THEY
WERE ALL FIRST GRADERS.
>> I DON'T KNOW YET.
I'LL EXAMINE IT TOMORROW
MORNING.
I DON'T THINK SO.
I HAVE NOT SEEN IT YET.
OKAY THE COMPANY WILL DEAL WITH
THAT, PHONE COMPANY IS GOING TO
HANDLE THAT ONE.
WE DISCUSSED THIS BRIEFLY WITH
THE STAFF BEFORE I CAME HERE.
THERE WAS, I BELIEVE, EVERYBODY
WAS HIT MORE THAN ONCE.
>> THE NATURE OF THE SHOOTING
WAS THERE A LOT OF CARE
TAKEN....
>> VERY DIFFICULT QUESTION TO
ANSWER.
>> AS FAR AS THE WOUNDS.
>> IT'S REALLY, YOU THINK AFTER
THE THOUSAND OF PEOPLE THAT ARE
SHOT, I COULD ANSWER THAT
QUESTION.
IF I ATTEMPTED TO ANSWER IT IN
IT COURT THERE WOULD BE AN
OBJECTION AND THEY WOULD WIN.
>> THEY WERE WEARING CUTE KID
STUFF.
IT'S THE KIND OF STUFF YOU WOULD
SEND YOUR KIDS OR GRANDKIDS OUT
THE DOOR TO FIRST GRADE IN.
THEY WERE SIMILAR TO THOSE WITH
THE CHILDREN.
>> THE DOCTOR, THAT YOU DID THE
AUTOPSY, WHERE ON THE BODIES WAS
THE WOUNDS?
>> ALL OVER.
ALL OVER.
PARDON?
I HAVE NOT EXAMINED HER YET.
THAT WILL BE TOMORROW MORNING.
I'LL LET THE SCENE GUYS ADDRESS
THAT ISSUE.
OBVIOUSLY I WAS AT THE SCENE AND
I'M EXPERIENCED IN THAT BUT
THERE ARE PEOPLE NUMBER ONE
PROFESSIONALS, I'LL LET THEM
COMMENT.
>> THE BODIES THAT YOU EXAMINED,
SEVEN?
>> THAT IS JUST THE ONES I DID.
I THINK THE GUYS AT THE CRIME
SCENE.
>> CAN YOU DESCRIBE HOW YOU DID
THE AUTOPSIES.
>> OUR GOAL WAS TO GET THE KIDS
OUT AND AVAILABLE TO TOT FUNERAL
DIRECTORS FIRST WELL, OBVIOUSLY.
>> HOW MANY BOYS AND HOW MANY
GIRLS?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
>> WERE YOU EMOTIONAL AT ANY
POINT WHERE YOU HAD TO...?
>> NOT YET.
YEAH, THERE HAVE BEEN TIMES IN
MY CAREER FOR REASONS I DON'T
APPRECIATE GOING INTO A LOCKER
ROOM AND ASSAULTING.
IF YOU DON'T HAVE TO DO THAT YOU
SHOULDN'T BE IN THIS BUSINESS.
FOR THIS ONE, NOT YET -- NOTICE
I SAID YET.
ALL RIGHT FOLKS, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
I HOPE Y'ALL PUT THIS ON YOUR
CALENDAR BECAUSE IN 31 YEARS, AS
CHIEF MEDICAL EXAMINER, THIS IS
ONLY THE SECOND PRESS CONFERENCE
I'VE GIVEN.
IT'S H. WAYNE CARVER AND IT'S
THE SECOND.
THAT IS WHY I DON'T USE THE
H. BECAUSE WHEN MY FATHER, MY
GRANDFATHER, HE SAID FINE AS
LONG AS YOU NEVER CALL HIM
HAROLD.
>> DID THEY SENT UP A TENT?
>> IT WASN'T A TENT.
IT WAS THIS THING.
IT'S SECTIONAL AND IT STICKS
TOGETHER WITH VELCRO AND
ELECTRICITY AND LIGHTS.
IT'S FROM THE DEPARTMENT OF
EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT.
THINK IT CAME FROM THE ARMY.
IT'S WHAT THEY USE FOR SETUP
FIELD HOSPITALS REALLY QUICKLY.
I DON'T KNOW.
NOT TERRYS HAVE BEEN CALLED.
-- MORTUARYS HAVE BEEN CALLED.
THE PAPERWORK HAS BEEN DONE.
FUNERAL HOMES CALL US AND AS
SOON AS THE PAPERWORK IS DONE WE
CALL THEM BACK.
THAT PROCESS WAS COMPLETED FOR
THE CHILDREN THAT WERE DONE.
>> TO WHERE?
>> OUR OFFICE IN FARMINGTON.
WE HAVE TRANSPORT VEHICLES.
>> HOW MANY VEHICLES?
>> WE HAVE THREE VEHICLES AND A
LOT OF GUYS TO DRIVE THEM.
>> ARE LE THEY ADVANCE?
>> ACTUALLY ONE THE HIGHLIGHTS
OF MY ADMINISTRATION IS THAT WE
MAKE THEM AS NONDESCRIPT AND
UNMARKED AS POSSIBLE.
WE STARTED OUT AT 6:00.
I DON'T HAVE THE DIFFERENTIAL.
>> Jamie: FOR ANYONE THAT IS
LISTENING, THIS IS MOST
DIFFICULT PRESS CONFERENCE I'VE
EVER WATCHED.
THIS IS THE MEDICAL EXAMINER
THAT EVALUATED THE SCENE AND
PORTAGE FACILITY WAS SET UP AT
THE SCHOOL.
HE EVALUATED PERSONALLY SEVEN OF
THESE CHILDREN DOING A POST MORE
TELL AND DESCRIBED IN
DEVASTATING DETAIL HOW THEIR
LIVES WERE TAKEN.
INNOCENT LIVES BY AS MANY AS 11
WOUNDS EACH.
THEY WERE CLEARLY HOMICIDES.
HE SAID IT WASN'T PROBABLY ONE
OF THE WORST TASKS HE HAS.
HE HAS 31 YEARS' EXPERIENCE AND
ALL THESE CHILDREN THEY
PHOTOGRAPHED THEY CHOSE TO DO IT
THAT WAY RATHER THAN HAVING
DIRECT BETWEEN THEM AND THEIR
PARENTS.
LET'S LISTEN TO THE AUTHORITIES.
>> THE TWO ADDITIONAL POST MORE
TELL EXAMINATIONS WILL BE
CONDUCTED TOMORROW DOCTOR
POST-MORTEM EXAMINATIONS WILL BE
DONE TOMORROW.
AS I STATED.
WE ARE ASKING PRIVACY FOR THE
FAMILIES AS WE STATED BEFORE.
COLONEL HAS IN FACT ASSIGNED A
TROOPER AND OFFICERS TO EACH
FAMILY TO PROVIDE AN OPEN LINE
OF COMMUNICATION TO THEM FROM
US.
THERE WILL BE THE FAMILIES AT
ALL TIMES IN AN EFFORT TO
INSTILL PRIVACY.
WE DO HAVE A LIST OF THE
DECEASED.
I ASK YOU TO SHARE.
WE'LL PUT IT UP ON OUR WEBSITE
IF YOU DON'T GET ONE.
WE SHOULD BE HANDING OUT AND
PLEASE TAKE ONE PER UNIT.
IF YOU DON'T GET ONE, IT WILL BE
ON THE WEBSITE WITHIN THE HOUR.
ANY SEARCH ENGINES THAT WILL
CONNECT YOU TO THE STATE POLICE
WEBSITE.
UNDERSTANDING PLEASE THIS IS
STILL AN ACTIVE CASE.
WE ARE STILL ACTIVELY PURSUING
LEADS AND ANTICIPATE TO DO SO
FOR THE NEXT 48 HOURS.
SIR?
WE DIDN'T DISCUSS THE LOCATION
OF ANY OF THE WEAPONRY AT ALL.
THERE HAS BEEN SPECULATION OUT
THERE RELATIVE TO THE LOCATION
OF THE WEAPONS.
WE WOULD LIKE TO DO THAT WHEN WE
HAVE ADDITIONAL INFORMATION TO
GIVE TO YOU ABOUT THE CALIBER,
ABOUT THE OWNERSHIP.
I'M GOING TO HOLD THAT QUESTION
UNTIL PROBABLY TOMORROW MORNING.
>> WHAT CAN YOU TALK ABOUT
PREVIOUS ALTERCATION IF IF B THE
GUNMAN?
>> I HAVE TO GET THAT
INFORMATION FOR YOU.
I DON'T KNOW.
THERE HAS BEEN TALK AND
SPECULATION ABOUT THAT, BUT IN
CONVERSATIONS WITH THE
SUPERINTENDENT AND AUTHORITIES
HERE IN TOWN.
THERE IS NO INFORMATION ABOUT
ANY CONFRONTATION.
THAT IS CERTAINLY SOMETHING WE
NEED TO LOOK AT.
OUR INVESTIGATORS WILL BEGIN
LOOK AT THE LAYERS AND ANSWER
ALL THOSE QUESTIONS IN THEIR
INVESTIGATIONS.
AGAIN, WE'LL HAVE TO EXAMINE
THAT, SIR.
>> DID THE ALTERCATION HAPPENED
OR THERE IS NO INFORMATION?
>> WE HAVE NO REPORTS FILED OF
ANY ALTERCATION INVOLVING THE
INDIVIDUAL IN THE SCHOOL.
I CAN TELL YOU WE HAVE NOT
OFFICIALLY IDENTIFIED HIM AT
THIS TIME.
UNTIL POSITIVE IDENTIFICATION WE
CAN'T DISCUSS ANY OF THE FACTS
AND CIRCUMSTANCES OF A DECEASED.
YES, SIR.
SPEAKING WITH SUPERINTENDENT
THERE WAS NO RELATION AT ALL.
ONE MORE QUESTION.
IT'S VERY IMPORTANT TO NOTE.
I WOULD BE NEGLECTFUL NOT TO
MENTION THIS, SUPPORT FROM
PEOPLE IN THE COMMUNITY BUT
ESPECIALLY IN THE COMMUNITY OF
NEWTOWN HAS BEEN OUTSTANDING.
THE SUPPORT OUTSIDE OF THE
COMMUNITY HAS BEEN MORE THAN
OUTSTANDING.
OUTPOURING OF ASSISTANCE AND
OUTPOURING OF HELP AS NEWTOWN
POLICE ARE INVOLVED AND FEDERAL
AUTHORITIES AND OTHER LOCAL
POLICE DEPARTMENTS.
OTHER PARA PROFESSIONALS.
THEY ARE ALL HERE AND SUPPORTED
THE FAMILY.
WE WILL HAVE AND PROVIDED
SUPPORT FOR THE FIRST RESPONDERS
FIRES, POLICE, EMS.
WE'LL CONTINUE TO DO THAT AND
CONTINUE TO DO THAT AS LONG AS
NECESSARY.
I'M SIMPLY GOING TO SAY YOU THIS
IS THE LAST BRIEFING FOR TODAY.
WE'LL BE HERE TOMORROW MORNING.
I'LL GIVE YOU ANY UPDATES
TOMORROW MORNING.
BUT THERE WILL BE NO MORE
BRIEFINGS.
IF ANYTHING WERE TO TO BREAK I
WOULD DIRECT YOU TO OUR WEBSITE.
WE WILL POST IT ON OUR WEBSITE.
WEE DON'T ANTICIPATE ANYTHING AS
OUR INVESTIGATORS CONTINUE OUR
WORK.
NO, THERE IS NOTHING MORE TODAY,
NOTHING MORALITY ALL.
WE DON'T KNOW, SIR.
I CAN'T DISCUSS.
THAT I'LL PROVIDE COPIES.
I HAVE SOME.
KELLY GRANT IS BACK THERE WITH
OTHER COPIES.
>> Rick: JOINING US NOW IS WOMAN
WHO HAS STUDIED INFAMOUS KILLERS
CHARLES WHITMAN AND UNIBOMBER
AND DISAPPEARANCE OF NATALEE
HOLLOWAY.
THAT WAS QUITE AN EXTRAORDINARY
PRESS CONFERENCE.
AS YOU LISTENED WITH YOUR
BACKGROUND BUT THE POLICE
LIEUTENANT, MEDICAL EXAMINER,
THE KINDS OF INJURIES THEY
SUSTAINED AND WEAPON USED TO
INFLICT THESE INJURIES, WHAT DO
YOU TAKE AWAY?
>> THE INFORMATION THAT THEY
WERE PUTTING OUT REALLY TAKES
YOUR BREATH AWAY.
WHAT HE SAID WAS THAT THESE
INJURIES WERE EXTREMELY SEVERE.
THEY WERE TISSUE INJURIES.
THE A.M. MISSION DID EXTENSIVE
DAMAGE.
THE VICTIMS WERE SHOT FROM THREE
TO 11 TIMES.
HE DIDN'T EXPLAIN, HE SAID THE
INJURIES WERE ALL OVER.
THE INJURIES WERE INFLICTED WHAT
I UNDERSTAND HIM TO SAY, WAS
WHICH REALLY TELLS ME THAT HE
WAS VERY INTENT ON MAKING SURE,
IT'S DIFFICULT TO SAY, HE WAS
MAKING SURE THAT HIS VICTIMS
DIED.
HE WANTED THEM DEAD.
THAT IS SOMEONE WHO WENT THERE
WITH THE INTENT TO KILL AS MANY
PEOPLE AS HE COULD.
IT'S REALLY STUNNING.
>> Rick: IT IS STUNNING.
ASSAULT RIFLE WAS ORIGINALLY
REPORTED TO HAVE BEEN LEFT IN
THE CAR.
HE USED IT AS HIS PRIMARY
WEAPON.
A WEAPON THAT I'M GUESSING MORE
SUITABLE FOR MILITARY COMBAT.
HERE HE WAS FIRST GRADE
CLASSROOM.
WHAT DOES IT SAY AS A PROFILER
TO YOU THAT HIS MAIN PRIMARY
TARGET WERE YOUNG CHILDREN?
>> THERE ARE NUMBER OF THINGS
THAT THAT SAYS.
NONE OF THEM ARE GOOD.
HE GOES INTO A SCHOOL WITH VERY
VULNERABLE VICTIMS, CHILDREN
THAT WOULD NOT KNOW WHAT TO DO,
NOT KNOW HOW TO RESPOND.
THEY ARE HELPLESS AND THEY ARE
CONTAINED IN A CLASSROOM.
SO HE ASSURED HIMSELF HE WAS
GOING TO BE ABLE TO KILL A
MAXIMUM NUMBER OF PEOPLE.
I THINK IT WAS CERTAINLY ONE OF
HIS MOTIVES.
FROM HIS PERSPECTIVE AND WE'LL
LEARN MORE AS THE INVESTIGATION
CONTINUES, THE IDEA THAT THESE
YOUNG PEOPLE WERE OBJECTS TO HIM
BECOMES MORE AND MORE IMPORTANT
TO ME.
TO BE ABLE TO DO THIS WITH SO
MANY PEOPLE WITH THAT KIND OF
WEAPON WITH THOSE KINDS OF
INJURIES GOING FROM CHILD TO
CHILD, IT WOULD BE ABSOLUTELY
ESSENTIAL HE WOULD VIEW THESE
VICTIMS NOT AS HUMAN BEINGS BUT
AS OBJECTS.
WHERE DO YOU DEVELOP THAT AS A
HUMAN BEING?
THAT IS TOTAL DIFFERENT
DISCUSSION.
THAT IS WHAT REALLY STRIKES ME
LISTENING TO THE EXTENT OF THOSE
VERY HORRIBLE INJURIES.
>> Rick: DR. MARY ELLEN O'TOOLE,
AUTHOR OF A BOOK CALLED
"DANGEROUS INSTINCTS."
>> Jamie: NEXT BRIEFING WILL BE
TOMORROW MORNING.
ANY NAY DEVELOPMENTS WE'LL GET
ON FOX NEWS CHANNEL.
I'M JAMIE COLBY.
>> Rick: I'M RICK FOLBAUM.
THANKS FOR JOINING US EVERYBODY.
♪
CONSTIPATED?
YEAH.
MM.
SOME LAXATIVES LIKE Dulcolax
CAN CAUSE CRAMPS.
BUT Phillips' Caplets
DON'T.
THEY HAVE MAGNESIUM.
FOR EFFECTIVE RELIEF
OF OCCASIONAL CONSTIPATION.
THANKS.
[ Phillips' Lady ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE WAY IT MOVES.
THE WAY IT CLEANS.
EVERYTHING ABOUT
THE ORAL-B POWER BRUSH
IS SIMPLY REVOLUTIONARY.
ORAL-B POWER BRUSHES OSCILLATE,
ROTATE
AND EVEN PULSATE
TO GENTLY LOOSEN AND BREAK UP
THAT STICKY PLAQUE
WITH MORE BRUSH MOVEMENTS
THAN MANUAL BRUSHES
AND EVEN
UP TO 50% MORE
THAN LEADING
SONIC TECHNOLOGY BRUSHES
FOR A SUPERIOR CLEAN.
ORAL-B POWER BRUSHES.
GO TO ORALB.COM
FOR THE LATEST OFFERS.