>> THE ENTIRE NATION IN
MOURNING AS WE LEARN BRAND NEW
DETAILS ABOUT THE 26 INNOCENT
VICTIMS DEPUNED DOWN IN SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU, I AM JOHN
SCOTT IN NEW YORK.
>> I AM GENA LEE 60 MILES FROM
WHERE JOHN IS.
IT IS REFLECTING AS WELL.
WE WERE ON THE AIR 11:00
EASTERN TIME WHEN WE FIRST
TART TOD UNDERSTAND WHAT WAS
TAKING PLACE IN SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE INFORMATION CAME OUT SO
SLOWLY AND SOME OF THE INITIAL
INFORMATION THAT WE RECEIVED
TURNED OUT TO BE FALSE.
WE EXPLAINED FOR OUR VIEWERS A
MOMENT AGO AND HOPEFULLY YOU
SAW THE MARY ANN AN JACOB.
SHE WAS ABLE TO GET THE 18
FOURTH GRADERS IN A STORAGE
CLOSE YEST PUSHED THE FILE CAB
NES AND HE HEARD THE BANGING
ON THE DOOR SHE DIDN'T WANT TO
OPEN UP.
SHED FOR THE BADGE TO BE
SLIPPED UNDERNEATH THE DOOR
BECAUSE THEY WERE SIMPLY
AFRAID AS WE ALL UNDERSTAND.
ONE THINGINGS THAT WE ARE
CONTINUING TO WATCH IN NEWTOWN
THE MEDIA STAGING AREA.
WE HEARD FROM THE STATE POLICE
AN HOUR AGO AND WE SHOULD BE
ERROR HEARING FROM THE
SUPERINTENDENT OF THE SCHOOLS
ANY TIME THIS HOUR.
WE ARE CRAVING FOR MORE
INFORMATION AND TRY TO PIECE
TOGETHER EXACTLY WHAT
HAPPENED.
>> IT IS MISTEROUS WHAT
MOTIVATED THE GUNMAN 20 YEAR
OLD ADAM LANZA FORCED HIS WAY
IN THE SCHOOL YESTERDAY
MORNING .
THIS IS A PICTURE FROM 2005.
HE IS SAID TO HAVE BEEN A VERY
SMART KID, BUT ONE WHO DIDN'T
ENGAGE A LOT WITH OTHER
STUDENTS, DESCRIBED BY SOME AS
A NERD AND A GOTH AND ONE WHO
DRESSED IN DARK COLORS.
SO MANY QUESTIONS ABOUT WHAT
LED THIS YOUNG MAN TO SNAP AND
GO ON THE RAMPAGE.
WE'LL TAKE YOU BACK TO
NEWTOWN.
PETER DOOCY WAS AT THE PRESS
CONFERENCE AND WE LEARNED A
LITTLE BIT ABOUT WHERE WE ARE
AT IN THE INVESTIGATION,
PETER.
>> JENNY, YOU AND JOHN TALK
BEING THE BIG QUESTION AMONG
EVERYBODY WHO IS HEART BROKEN.
CLASS MATES ANDCO WORKERS AND
WHY.
WHY DID A TWEN YEAR OLD GO IN
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND SHOOT
20 STUDENTS AND SIX ADULTS.
IT SOUNDS LIKE POLICE HAVE A
LOT OF THE EVIDENCE AND THEY
WANT TO KNOW WHAT CAUSED THIS
AND THE MOVE IVE AND THERE IS
A LOT OF EVIDENCE INSIDE OF
THE SCHOOL, THE WEAPONS WERE
RECOVERED NOT TO FAR AWAY FROM
THE GUNMAN'S DECEASED BODY
AFTER HE SHOT HIMSELF.
AND A LOT OF EVIDENCE OUTSIDE.
EVERY CAR IS PARK ARE THE
CRIME SCENE AND THERE IS A LOT
OF EVIDENCE IN THE SECONDARY
LOCATION WHICH IS WHERE THIS
GUNMAN SHOT HIS MOTHER AND WE
HAVE A BITE FROM THE CHIEF OF
POLICE.
>> OUR INVESTIGATORS IN THE
CRIME SCENE AND SECONDARY
CRIME SCENE WHERE THE FEMALE
WAS LOCATED DECEASED DID
PRODUCE VERY GOOD EVIDENCE IN
THIS INVESTIGATION AND OUR
INVESTIGATORS WILL BE USE IN
PAPING THE COMPLETE PICTURE AS
TO HOW AND MORE PERSONLY WHY
THIS OCCURRED.
AND SOMETHING ELSE THEY SAID
GENA IS GOING TO BE CRITICAL
IN THE INVESTIGATION, THE
COUNT OF THE SINGLE SURVIVORS
AND ONE ADULT WOMAN WHO WAS
SHOT AND SURVIVED.
SHE IS RECOVERING WELL AND
SOUNDS LIKE WHATEVER SHE TELLS
THE AUTHORITIES WILL HELP THEM
A LOT AND PIECE THINTHS
TOGETHER.
>> THERE WERE HEROS.
MARY NAN JACOBS KEEPING HER
KIDS SAFE.
SHE CALLED THE SECRETARY A
HERO AND SHE CALLED THE OFFICE
AND HEARD OVER THE
INNERCOMSOMETHING WAS GOING
ON.
IT SEEMS LIKE THERE ARE FOLKS
OUT THERE THAT ARE TRULY
HERORIC ALSO THE PROCESS OF
WHAT IT IS LIKE TO GATHER NEWS
ON THIS STORY.
>> WE ARE TOLD INITIALLY WHEN
THE CALLS CAME OUT THERE WAS A
SHOOTING IN THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
ON DUTY AND OFF DUTY OFFICERS
ALL RESPONDED AND WE HAVE BEEN
HEARING REPORTS OF SHATTERED
GLASS AND WE LEARNED THAT ALL
OF THAT EXTRA SHATTERED GLASS
IS BECAUSE THE SAME WAY THE
GUNMAN HAD TO FORCE HIMSELF IN
THE SCHOOL SINCE THEY DIDN'T
WANT HIM IN THERE, THE POLICE
AND ON DUARTEDUTY POLICE
OFFICERS HAD TO FORCE
THEMSELVES BECAUSE THE SCHOOL
WAS ON LOCK DOWN AND TICHERS
AND STUDENTS WERE SO SCARED
AND WITH ALL OF THE FOURTH
GRADERS, YOU HEARD THEY CANNOT
WANT TO OPEN THE DOOR UNTIL
THE POLICE GOT THERE UNTIL
THEY SAW A BADGE.
IT DIFFICULT TO GATHER NEWS ON
THIS, WHEN YOU HEAR THE STORE
TORES AND TALK TO THE
COLLEAGUES AND THE LIBRARY
CLERK TOLD US HOW IT WAS NOT
UNTIL AT A GOT TO THE FIRE
HOUSE AND LOOKING CLASS BY
CLASS, ALL OF THE STUDENTS ARE
LINED YUP TWO FIRST GRADE
CLASSES THAT WERE NOT THERE.
ONLY A FEW STUDENTS WERE
PRESENT OUT OF TWO ENTIRE
CLASSES AND WHEN YOU LOOK AT
THE NUMBERS, IT IS STAGGERING.
AND INFORMATION FOR THEM.
AND WE WERE SPEAKING TO THE
LOCAL JOURNALIST AND THEY WERE
OVERCOME WITH EMOTION AS TO
WHAT HAPPENED IN THEIR
COMMUNITY.
NYEAH.
IT IS DIFFICULT, AND IT IS ONE
OF THOSE THINGS, WHERE IT IS
IT A VERY, VERY MAUL TOWN, AND
EVERYONE.
AS SOMEBODY WHO IS THE HUSBAND
OF A TEACHER OF ANOTHER SCHOOL
IN THE DISTRICT.
NORMAL LOW WHEN YOU HEAR ABOUT
A WORLD EVENT IT IS IT DEGREES
OF.
AND HERE IT IS IT ONE DEGREE.
THE NAMES OF THE VICTIMS WILL
NOT BE RELEASED UNTIL THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER IS FINISHED
WITH WORK.
THEY ARE ALL IDENTIFIED AND
REMOVED FROM THE SCHOOL.
BUT THE MEDICAL EXAMINER STILL
HAS WORK TO DO.
BUT THE FEAR THAT IS GRIPPING
THE FOLKS, WHEN THOSE COME OUT
OF THE 20 CHILDREN AND 6
ADULTS, IT IS GOING TO BE
SOMEBODY THAT THEY ARE
POTENTIALLY VERY CLOSE TOMPT
>> 20 YEARS 5-TEP YEARS OLD.
JOHN, AS PETER POINTED OUT TO
US.
YOU MENTIONED MARY ANN JACOB
AND WE GO BACK TO THAT TORE
STORE BECAUSE IT WAS ONE OF
THE MOST DETAILED FIRST HAND
ACCOUNT THAT WE RECEIVED TODAY
.
SHOW JUSTED HOW TIGHT-KNIT THE
COMMUNITY.
MARY ANN, HER CHILDREN WENT TO
THE ELEMENTARY COOL.
AND SHE WAS PRESIDENT OF THE
PTA AND SHE RETURNED AND
WORKED THERE FOUR-FIVE YEARS
IN THE LIBRARY WHILE HER
CHILDREN GO TO THE NEIGHBORING
HIGH SCHOOL.
YOU CAN JUST SEE FROM THAT ONE
EXAMPLE HOW CLOSE-KNIT THE
COMMUNITY IS.
NAND TALKING ABOUT THE HEROS
AND THE PRINCIPAL AND A SCHOOL
PSYCHICOLOGIST AND IN A MEET
THEY RAN BOO THE HALLWAY TO
TRY TO STOP THE COMMOTION AND
SHOT DEAD THERE.
NEWS UNFOLDED YESTERDAY.
DETAILS AND CONFLICTING
REPORTS FLOODED IN THROUGHOUT
THE DAY.
HERE IS A TIME LINE OF THE
EVENTS AS WE LEARNED THEM
YESTERDAY.
>> BREAKING NEW TO TELL YOU
ABOUT RIGHT NOW.
THERE IS REPORTS OF A SCHOOL
SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WE KNOW FEW DETAILSMENT STATE
POLICE RESPONDED TO A REPORT
OF A SHOOTING IN SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL .
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADE.
>> A DISPATCHER WITH A NEWTOWN
VOLUNTARILY AMBULANCE CORP
SAID ONE TEACHER WAS
TRANSPORTED TO A NEARBY
HOSPITAL POSSIBLE WITH A GUN
SHOT WOUND .
>> IT IS DIFFICULT TO SEE IF
ONE OF THE WAT TEEMS THAT WAS
REPONDING AND ARMORED VEHICLES
HEADING TO THE COLASK THEY
RACE TO NEWTOWN FROM ALL OVER
CONNECTICUT.
>> ONE GUNMAN, MAYBE TWO AND
TWO RESPECTS THAT ONE GUNMAN
MAY BE DEAD.
AS YOU CAN UNDERSTAND IT IS A
FAST-MOVING AND FLUID
SITUATION IN THE SCHOOL.
>> IT IS IT IMPORTANT ON A DAY
LIKE TODAY TO VIEW THIS AS I
KNOW THE PRESIDENT AS A FATHER
DOES AND I AS A FATHER AND
OTHERS WHO ARE PARENTS.
CERTAINLY DO, WHICH IS TO FEEL
ENORMOUS SYMPATHY FOR FAMILIES
THAT ARE AFFECTED AND TO DO
EVERYTHING WE CAN.
NSOURCES ARE TELLING FOX NUSE
THAT 26 PEOPLE ARE DEAD AT
THIS POINT.
8 ADULTS INCLUDING THE
CHILDREN AND 18 CHILDREN.
THEY HEARD THE GUN SHOTS AND
THEY ARE TRYING TO UNDERSTAND
WHAT HAPPENED.
AND WE TELL THEM IN DETAILS IT
IS GOING TO BE MUCH WORSE.
>> ONE SOURCE SUGGESTED THAT
THE YOUNG MAN MAY HAVE BEEN A
YOUNG MAN 20 YEARS OLD AND MAY
LIVE IN NEW JERSEY AND MAY BE
A SEPARATE SITUATION AND CRIME
SCENE WHERE THEY KICKED DOWN
THE DOOR OF THAT PERSON'S
HOPE.
WE ARE TRYING TO CONFIRM THAT
AT THIS HOUR .
WE DON'T KNOW THE IDENTITY OF
THE GUNMAN.
THERE WERE FATALITIES AT THE
SCENE.
STUDENTS AND STAFF.
THERE IS IT NO INFORMATION
RELEASED AT THIS TIME UNTIL WE
HAVE PROPER NOTIFICATION.
>> IT IS IT SHEER TERROR AND,
AND, A SENSE OF IMMEDIATE
URIGENCEY TO GET TO YOUR CHILD
AND PROTECT THEM.
>> THE PRESIDENT IS SET TO
MAKE REMARK ABOUT THE
SHOOTING.
LET'S LISTEN.
NTHIS AFTERNOON I SPOKE TO
GOVERNOR MALLOY AND FBI
DIRECTOR MUELLER AND OFFERED
MY CONDOLENCES ON BEHALF OF
THE NATION AND MADE IT CLEAR
HE WILL HAVE EVERY SINGLE
RISOURCE TO INVESTIGATE THE
HEINOUS CRIME, CARE FOR THE
VICTIMS, COUNSEL THEIR
FAMILIES.
AS RESPECTED THERE WERE
FATALITIES, THERE WERE 18
CHILDREN PRONOUNCED DEAD AT
THE SCHOOL.
TWO TRANSPORTED TO AREA HELPS
AND PRONOUNCED DEAD AT AREA
HOSPITALS AND SIX ADULTS
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCENE
OF THE SCHOOL.
>> AND THIS HAPPENED SIX HOURS
AGO.
AND THERE IS IT A LOT OF
EVIDENCE PROCESSED AND ALL OF
THE SCENES ARE INVESTIGATED
INCLUDING A APPARENTLY THE
HOME OF THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER
IN NEWTOWN WHERE AN ADULT BODY
WAS.
THERE ARE CONFLICTING RESPECTS
ABOUT THE AT THAT TIMUS OF THE
SHOOTER'S FATHER AND CONFLICT
BEING REPORTS ON THE SHOOTER
HIMSELF.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN .
BEAUTIFUL KIDS BETWEEN THE
ANALS OF 5-10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM, BIRTHDAYS,
GRADUATIONS, WEDDINGS, AND
KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS, MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES TO HELPING
OUR CHILDREN FULFILL THEIR
DREAMS AND OUR HEARTS ARE
BROKEN TODAY FOR THE PARENT
DEPLAND IMPORTANTAS AND'RES
AND BROTHERS OF THIS LITTLE
CHILDREN AND THE FAMILIES THAT
WERE LOST.
THE NATION WONDERS HOW ONE MAN
CAN GO ON A RAMPAGE AND
CARNAGE.
THE ADULTS HELPED TO CIPH THE
CHILDREN AND PREVENT THE
CATASTROPHE FROM EVEN ACCIDENT
WORSE.
GENA.
NIT WAS A DIFFICULT TORE STORE
AND HAS BEEN A DIFFICULT STORY
AND CHALLENGING TO SAY THE
LEAST TO REPORT OUT.
ONE OF THE FIRST LESSONS YOU
LEARN AS A YOURNALIST.
FIRST REPORTS THAT YOU GET ARE
MOST INACCURATE.
OF THE HEROS WANTED THINGS
THAT WE LATER TOUND WERE NOT
TRUE.
AND YOU CAN SHARE THE LIGHT ON
THIS AS WELL.
TALK ABOUT THE THINGS WE NOW
LEARNED.
Y WA THE SHOOT ARES NAME IS
ADAM LANZA AND THE FATHER WAS
DEAD.
AND THOOTHAT IS NOT TRUE.
AS WE KNOW NOW.
AND ON THE AIR, FIRST HEARD
THAT THERE MIGHT BE TWO
SHOOTERS ON THE SCENE AND WE
LATER LEARNED AT LEAST
ACCORDING TO THE REPORTS NOW
THAT THAT IS NOT TRUE.
>> IN THE EARLY PART OF THESE
INVESTIGATIONS.
THERE MIGHT BE MULTIPLE PHONE
CALL TO 911 AND YOU GET
DIFFERING DESCRIPTIONS AND I
SUPPOSE THAT'S THE REASON THAT
THEY THOUGHT WERE TOOTWO --
TWO SHOOTERS.
ADAM LANZA CARRIED THE ID OF
RYAN LANZA WHO IS FOUR YEARS
OLD AND APPARENTLY ACCORDING
TO THE MEDIA REPORTS HAS NOT
ACTUALLY SPOKE TONE HIS
YOUNGER BROTHER IN ABOUT TWO
YEARS.
I HAVE TO PRESUME THAT THAT
WAS BY DESIGN.
HE WANTED TO HELP CONFUSE LAW
ENFORCEMENT AS TO THE IDENTITY
OF THE MAN THEY WERE LOOKING
AT.
AND ESPECIALLY IN THE AGE OF
TWITTER AND BOOK BOCK.
A LOT OF INFORMATION CAME OUT
FROM THOSE SOURCES AND IT WAS
NOT NECESSARILY ACCURATE.
>> RIGHT.
>> WE STRUGGLE TO GET THE BEST
INFORMATION THAT WE CAN TO OUR
VIEWERS IN A SITUATION AWFUL
LIKE NTHANK YOU VERY MUCH IT
IS ONE OF THE QUESTIONS THAT
SO MANY OF US ARING.
WE KEEP GOING BACK TO WHAT
MAKES A PERSON DO THIS?
SO MANY WORDS.
SOME CALL TRAGEDY AND IT IS IT
A MURDER OF OUR MOST INNOCENT.
DOCTOR, PICKING UP ON THE
CONVERSATION THAT YAWN AND I
JUST HAD ABOUT STAYING CLOSE
TO THE FACTS.
WHERE DO YOU START HERE?
>> EVERYONE OF US, PARTNERS, -
PARENTS AND CITIZENS AND
COMMUNITY MEMBERS AND FRIENDS
.
WE ARE ALL PARTNERS OF NEWTOWN
CHILDREN.
SINCE MY EARLY DAYS OF YALE
AND I AM FROM THAT AREA AND I
EXTRA SENSE OF PAIN.
NOW TO YOUR QUESTION,
THE FACTS ARE,
AS IN AURORA AND AS IN ARIZONA
AND VIRGINIA TECH AS IN
VIRTUALLY EVERY SINGLE CASE
THAT THE SECRET SERVICE
CONDUCTED.
IS IT IS PRECEDED BY AN
UNDIAGNOSED AND UNTREATED
MENAL ILLNESS.
WE NEED TO BE CAREFUL WITH
INFORMATION THAT OVER THE LAST
24 HOURS, INCREASING
INFORMATION CAME IN FROM
FAMILY MEMBERS, FROM FRIENDS
AND FROM STUDENTS.
THAT ADAM LANZA AS YOU HAVE
MENTIONED WAS DISTURBED AND
REMOVED, AND ISOLATED AND THE
FACT MATTER IS, LIKE AURORA,
LIKE ARIZONA, LIKE VIRGINIA
TECH, THAT IS THE KEY
DIAGNOSTIC SIGN OF SOMEONE WHO
IS 20 YEARS OLD OF A MACHINE
WHO IS DELUSIONAL.
AND RIULENT AND PARINOID AND
ABLE TO COMMIT SUCH A HORRIFIC
ACT.
MOST SCHIZOPHRENIA PEOPLE ARE
NOT RIULENT BUT IT IS WHAT WE
HAVE SEEN IN HOMES AND WHAT WE
MAY SEE IN THIS CASE.
>> DOCTOR AS YOU POINTED OUT.
WE MAY SEE IN THIS CASE.
AND YOU POINT TO SIGNIFICANT
PATTERNS.
NTHERE EING SIGNS.
NTHERE ARE, BUT HOW SHOULD WE
NAVIGATE THIS?
WE WANT TO PROVIDE AND EXPLAIN
A BIT OF WHAT HAPPENED HERE
BUT DON'T WANT TO USE
DIAGNOSISS TO JUSTIFY THE
ACTIONS.
HELP US WITH THAT.
>> IT IS IT VERY CLEAR WAY OF
JUSTIFYING DIAGNOSIS DO NOT
JUSTIFY AND AS LONG AS WE
THINK THAT WE WILL NOT BE ABLE
TO PREVENT THE EVEBS.
DIAGNOSIS PROVIDE THE
EXPLANATION .
WHEN CHOIN VIRGINIA TECH WAS
PARINOID AND GATHERING HIS
BODY ARMOR AND WEAPONS AND
PREPARING HIS ASSAULT.
HE WAS DOING THAT BECAUSE HE
WAS PARINOID.
IF HE WAS PROPERLY TREATED AT
THAT TIME, THAT EVEP WOULD NOT
HAVE OCCURRED.
HOL MES WAS PREPARING HIS
APARTMENT FOR A EXPLOSION TO
ENLEASH ON THE MOVIE THEATER
HIS PSYCHIATRIST KNEW AND WAS
CONCERNED ABOUT TEMPERATURE IF
IT WAS PREVENTED, IT WOULD NOT
HAPPEN.
THE TIME HAS COME FOR US RAZZ
MERPS, AS -- AS AMERICANS AND
CITIZENS AND IDENTIFY THEM AND
SEE THEM AND PREVENT THEM AND
SO THAT BEE DON'T NEED -- WE
DON'T NATIONS LEAK TODAY THAT
OUR CHILDREN ARE GRIVING FOR
THE COUNTRY.
>> WE CAN PREVENT THESENTIOUS
VENS FROM OCCURRING, IF WE
WILL TEACH PEOPLE EDUCATORS
AND PARENTS WE CAN DO THIS.
IT IS IT A NATIONAL.
>> YOU GIVE US A LOT TO AND WE
APPRECIATE YOUR INSIGHT.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US ON A
DAY LIKE TODAY, YAWN WE WATCH
THE BREAKING NEWS EMERGE.
>> WE ARE LEARNING THAT THE
SCHOOL SHOOTER ADAM LANZA WAS
NOT LET IN THE BUILDING POLICE
SAY HE FORCED HIS WAY IN AND
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
HAD REPORTED LIE INSTALL WOULD
A NEW SECURITY SYSTEM.
WHAT ELSE CAN SCHOOLS DO TO
PROTECT THE SCHOOLS?
WE'LL HAVE THE ANSWERS NEXT.
>> IT IS HORRIBLE THAT SUCH
EVIL EXIST IN THE UNITED
STATES AND IN SANDY HOOK IN
PARTICULAR .
THAT'S THE NATURE OF THE WORLD
WE LIVE IN,IX.
♪
Sometimes what we suffer from
Is bigger than we think ...
like the flu.
With aches, fever and chills-
the flu's a really big deal.
So why treat it like
it's a little cold?
There's something
that works differently
than over-the-counter
remedies.
Prescription TAMIFLU attacks
the flu virus at its source.
So don't wait. Call your
doctor right away.
TAMIFLU is prescription
medicine for treating the flu
in adults and children
one year and older
whose flu symptoms started
within the last two days.
Before taking TAMIFLU tell your
doctor if you're pregnant,
nursing. have serious
health conditions,
or take other medicines.
If you develop an allergic
reaction, a severe rash,
or signs of unusual behavior,
stop taking TAMIFLU and call
your doctor immediately.
Children and adolescents in
particular may be at an
increased risk
of seizures, confusion
or abnormal behavior.
The most common
side effects are
mild to moderate nausea
and vomiting.
The flu comes on fast,
so ask your
doctor about TAMIFLU.
Prescription for flu.
♪
ON FOX NUSE WE REPORT FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, ONE
ACCOUNTS THAT WE CONTINUALLY
RETURN TO IS A WOMAN WHO WAS
WALKING WITH HER HUSBAND IN A
FIELD BEHIND ME AND SHE CAME
UPON THE NEWS VEHICLES.
SHE IS A LIBRARY CLERK WHO WAS
INSIDE OF THE SCHOOL WITH 18
FOURTH GRADERS WHEN THE SHOTS
FIRST RANG OUT.
ONE OF THE THINGS SHE TOLD US
THE SCHOOL IN THE YEARS SHE
WORKED FOR HAD PRACTICED.
THEY PRACTICED AND THEY KNEW
WHAT TO DO.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> I THINK THE KIDS WERE
SCARED BUT THEY ARE SCARED
WHEN IT IS A DRILL.
THE FIRE ALARM GOES OFF AND IT
IS SCARY FOR THE LITTLE KIDS.
I DON'T THINK UNTIL WE OPENED
THE DOOR AND THERE WERE COPS
WITH GIANTIC GUNS AND ESCORTED
THEM OUT DID THEY REAL.
>> WHAT WERE THE CHILDREN
SAYING IN THE CLOSEST.
NHOW LONG DID THAT TAKE?
>> WE DIDN'T KNOW AND WE LET
THEM IN AT FIRST.
THEY FOUNDED ON THE
THAPE WERE PLOSE AND THEY PUT
A BADGE FROM UNDER THE DOOR
AND WE LET THE KIDS OUT THEN.
WE GOT TO THE FIRE HOUSE AT
TIN TIME 30.
NYOU WERE THERE AN HOUR.
NI THINK SO.
NJOHN, MARY ANN US THEY HAD
GONE OVER THE DIFFERENT DRILLS
AND SHE WAS WITH THE 18 FOURTH
GRADERS AND TIGHT AS WE WERE
AROWN TRYING TO TALK TO HER.
AND ONE OF THE LUCKY THINGS,
IN THAT TORAGE CLOSEST THEY
HAD CRAYIONS AND PAPER AND
THEY TROYED TO GET THE KIDS TO
DRAW AND WORRY THEIR
QUESTIONS.
>> IT STATE YOUR NAMELY SOUNDS
LIKE SHE AND THE OTHER
TEACHERS DID A FANTASTIC JOB
OF KEEPING THE KIDS SAFE AS
THEY COULD.
THERE IS A REPORT OF IANITOR
RUNNING THROUGH THE HALLS
WARNING TEACHER TO KEEP THEIR
DOORS CLOYCED BECAUSE OF THE
SHOOTING.
TO MY KNOWLEDGE WE DON'T KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED TO THE JANITOR
AND WHETHER HE SURVIVED.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY HAD
INSTALL A NEW SECURITY SYSTEM
AND COORDINATING LOCK DOWN
DRILLS.
DESPITE THE CAUTION THE GUNMAN
GOT N. >> WE'LL TALK ABOUT IT
WITH MICHAEL DORM.
IT IS IT A NONPROFIT
ORGANIZATION THAT HELPS COOLS
IMPROVE CRISIS PREPAREDNESS
AND CAMPUS SAFETY.
>> WOULD YOU SAY GIVEN WHAT WE
KNOW STOW FAR, THIS SCHOOL DID
A PRESIDENTY GOOD JOB OF
TAKING CARE OF THIS
UNIMAGINABLE SITUATION.
>> FIRST ALL OF OUR ANALYST
AND VOLUNTEERS WOULD LIKE TO
EXPRESS CONDOLENCES FOR THE
TERRIBLE, TERRIBLE QUESTION.
I HAVE DONE FONCE --
FORERENCIC EVASIONS AND IT IS
EARLY TO TELL.
I AM SEEING INDICATIONS OF A
NUMBER OF GOOD THINGS THEY AM
HEARING.
ONE TO UNDERSTAND, A SIMPLE
ERROR CAN DRAMATICALLY CHANGE
THE CASULTIES DELAY OF LOCKING
A DOOR IN A LOCK DOWN IT CAN
CHANGE THE OUTCOME.
IT IS EARLY TO TELL.
A LOT OF THE THINGS I AM
HEARING AND WHY HAVE TO
REMEMBER THAT NOTHING IS IT
FOOL PROOF.
INE OUR BEST EFFORTS CAN'T
PROTECT US FROM SOME
SITUATIONS .
NWE UNDERSTAND FROM THE TIME
LINE THAT POLICE RELEASED THAT
THE GUNMAN SHOT AND KILLED HIS
OWN MOTHER.
IMAGINE THE DEPRAVITY THERE
CAN HEADS TO THE SCHOOL WITH
THE INTENTION OF OPENING FIRE.
EVEN A LOCKED SCHOOL DIDN'T
KEEP HIM OUT.
NOW THAT IS IT PRETTY MUCH
ROUTINE.
THIS SCHOOL WAS LOCKED AND WE
HEARD FROM LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE HE APARENTLY SHOT HIS
WAY IN AND MASHED HIS WAY IN
TO OPEN THE DOR.
THAT IS RESPONSIBLE FOR THE
PART OF THE SCHOOL IT SEEMS.
NWE HAVE TO LOOK AT YOUR
WEAKEST HAPPENING LINTH'RE
LINK.
IF YOU HAVE GLASS AND SOMEONE
SHOOTS OUT A WIPO AND SCHOOLS
DON'T REALIZE THEY HAVE TO PUT
PROTECTIVE LAMINATE ON THE
CLASS .
WE DON'T KNOW IF IT WOULD HAVE
MAID A DIFFERENCE.
I WORKED WITH LIEUTENANT VANCE
BEFORE AND HE IS A SHARP IPO
AND THEY ARE GETTING OUT
INFORMATION QUICKLY FOR THE
MAG MAGNITUDE OF THE DETAILS.
WE FOCUS ON EVIDENCE BASED
APPROACHES OF HOW PEOPLE
ACCOUNT UNDER STRESS .