>> GOOD MORNING EVERYONE.
I AM PATTI ANN BROWNE.
>> I AM HEATHER CHILDERS.
IT IS MONDAY DECEMBER 17TH.
THANK YOU FOR WATCHING "FOX &
FRIENDS FIRST".
>> A TRYING DAY FOR NEWTOWN
CONNECTICUT FOR THE WHOLE
COUNTRY AS FUNERALS WIARE BEING
HELD FOR THE VICTIMS OF THE
HORRIFIC SCHOOL SHOOTING.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA OFFERED
COMFORT AND SUPPORT FOR THE HAVE
YOU BEENING TIM'S FAMILIES.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA CAME TO
NEWTOWN LAST NIGHT.
HE WAS TRYING TO COMFORT THE
FAMILIES OF THOSE WHO HAVE
CHILDREN WHO WENT TO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
HE WENT TO THE CLASSROOMS BEFORE
HIS NATURAL ADDRESS AND
PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG'S
DAUGHTER THAT HAD A CAPTION MY
MOM WOULD BE SO PROUD TO SEE
PRESIDENT OBAMA HOLDING HER
GRANDDAUGHTER BUT NOT AS PROUD
AS I AM OF HER.
6-YEAR-OLD EMILIE PARKER'S
FAMILY POSTED PICTURES AS WELL.
SOME OF THEM VERY SOME DER
OTHERS WITH HER YOUNG SIBLING
ARE FULL OF SMILESMENT AFTER THE
MEETINGS IN THE CLASSROOM THE
PRESIDENT TOLD NEW TOWN THAT THE
NATION'S HEART WAS BROKEN FOR
THEIR LOSS.
>> AS A COMMUNITY YOU HAVE
INSPIRED US, NEWTOWN.
IN THE FACE OF INDESCRIBABLE
CENTER LINES, IN THE FACE OF
UNCONSCIONABLE EVIL, YOU LOOKED
OUT FOR EACH OTHER.
YOU CARED FOR ONE ANOTHER.
YOU HAVE LOVED ONE AN IS HOW NE
REMEMBERED.
>> EARLIER YESTERDAY AUTHORITIES
TOLD US THAT HUNDREDS OF ROUNDS
WERE FIRED HERE ON FRIDAY.
THE PRESIDENT SAID IT IS NOW
TIME TO BETTER PROTECT THE
CHILDREN WHO CANNOT PROTECT
THEMSELVES.
>> CAN WE HONESTLY SAY WE ARE
DOING ENOUGH TO KEEP OUR
CHILDREN ALL OF THEM SAFE FROM
HARM.
WE CLAIM AS A NATION THAT WE ARE
ALL TOGETHER THERE, LETTING THEM
KNOW WE ARE LOVED AND TEACH TO
GO LOVE IN RETURN.
ARE WE TRULY DOING ENOUGH TO
GIVE ALL THE CHILDREN OF THIS
COUNTRY A CHANCE THEY DESERVE TO
LIVE OUT THEIR LIVES IN
HAPPINESS AND WITH PURPOSE.
I HAVE BEEN REFLECTING ON THIS
THE LAST FEW DAYS.
IF WE ARE HONEST WITH OURSELVES,
THE ANSWER IS NO.
>>> I WAS AT A BAR THAT WAS
FREQUENTED BY THE SUSPECT'S
MOTHER NANCY LANZA.
THERE WERE MANY PEOPLE AT THE
HANGOUT FOR FOLKS IN THE TOWN TO
GO IN NEWTOWN.
NOT ONE PERSON SAID ONE THING
THE ENTIRE TIME.
IT WAS COMPLETELY SILENT.
PEOPLE HUNG ON EVERY WORD OF
EVERY PRAYER AND EVERY WORD OF
THE PRESIDENT'S REPARKS.
AFTERWARDS I ASKED THE MAN WHO
WAS VERY EMOTIONAL WHAT HE
THOUGHT ABOUT THE SPEECH AND HE
SAID HE THOUGHT IT WAS GREAT.
HE JUST HOPES THE PRESIDENT
FOLLOWS THROUGH ON THAT CALL TO
ACTION, WHATEVER THAT ACTION
ENDS UP BEING.
>> THAT IS THE QUESTION, WHAT
ANSWER.
PETER DOOCY LIVE IN WASHINGTON.
>> LAWMAKERS ON BOTH SIDES OF
THE AISLE ARE VOWING TO TAKE
STEPS TO TRY TO KEEP THAT TYPE
OF TRAGEDY FROM HAPPENING AGAIN.
KELLY WRIGHT IS LIVE WITH MORE.
>>> LAW AMERICAS AS WELL AS THE
PRESIDENT AFFECTED BY THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING TRAGEDY.
AS THE PRESIDENT SPOKE OUT TO
CONSOLE THE RESIDENTS OF NEWTOWN
HE WANTS TO TAKE MEANINGFUL
ACTION FOR SUCH TRAGEDIES IN THE
FUTURE.
>>> IN THE COMING WEEKS I WILL
USE WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE
HOLDS TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW
CITIZENS TO LAW ENFORCEMENT TO
MENTAL HEALTH PROFESSIONALS TO
PARENTS AND EDUCATORS IN AN
EFFORT AIMED AT STOPPING MORE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS.
>> FLAGS ARE HALF STAFF FOR
CHILDREN AND TEACHES WHO DIED IN
THIS SENSELESS SHOOTING.
REPUBLICANS ARE VOWING TO TAKE
ACTION.
>> I THINK WE NEED A NATIONAL
COMMISSION ON MASS VIOLENCE NOT
TO BE IN PLACE OF ANYTHING ELSE
THE PRESIDENT OR CONGRESS OR
STATE GOVERNMENTS MIGHT WANT TO
DO, BUT TO MAKE SURE THE
HEARTBREAK AND THE ANGER THAT WE
FEEL NOW IS NOT DISSIPATED
OVERTIME OR LOST IN THE
LEGISLATIVE GRIDLOCK.
>> WE DEAL WITH THE
RAMIFICATIONS AND THE
BOMBARDMENT AND MEDIACY BETWEEN
VIOLENCE, THE REALISM THAT YOU
GAIN IN MOVIES.
THE TEEN YEARS AND ADULT HOOD
MADE THE TRANSITION IT DOES NEED
HELP.
WE LASS LOOK TO FAMILIES AND
COMMUNITIES AND CHURCHES IT'S
NOT JUST A GOVERNMENT SOLUTION.
>> LIEUTENANT GOVERN NO DAN
MALLOY ALSO SAID THAT.
HE SAID THE COUNTRY NEEDS TO
TAKES STEPS OR STEP UP IT'S WORK
ON MENTAL HEALTH AND CRISIS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA ADDING WE CAN'T
ACCEPT EVENTS LIKE THIS AS
ROUTINE.
>> THAT IS FOR SURE.
>> YOU ARE WELCOME.
>> YOUR TOP FIVE STORIES AT THIS
HOUR.
OTHER NEWS TODAY TWO KANSAS
POLICE OFFICERS HAVE BIDE DIED E
LINE OF DUTY AT THE TOPEKA
GROCERY STORE.
THE GUNMAN IS STILL ON THE LOSE.
A MANHUNT IS ON THE HUNT FOR
THIS MAN.
COPS SAY THE OFFICERS WERE
INVESTIGATING CALLS FOR
SUFFICIENT VEHICLES WHEN
TUSKARINO OPENED FIRE.
HE THIS KILLED A CORPORAL WHO
RECENTLY RETIRED FROM THE
MILITARY AND A 29-YEAR-OLD WHO
JUST JOINED THE FORCE LAST YEAR.
>>> AN INDIANA MAN WAS RAISED
AFTER FINDING 47 GUNS IN HIS
HOME WHICH SITS NEXT TO AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WHERE HIS WIFE
WORKS.
HE THREATENED TO SET HIS WIFE ON
FIRE THEN SAID HE WOULD GO TO
THE SCHOOL AND KILL AS MANY
PEOPLE AS POSSIBLE.
AS A PRECAUTION POLICE ARE
ADDING RESPECT AT ALL OF THE
LOBI --
ADDING SECURITY FOR THIS WEEK.
>>> NEW REPORTS SAY THE HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER IS WILLING
TO RAISE THE TOP TAX RATE ON
AMERICANS MAKING MORE THAN 1
MILLION A YEAR AND IS OFFERING
$1 TRILLION IN HIGHER TAX
REVENUE OVER TEN YEARS.
BOEHNER WOULD CONSIDER RAISING
THE DEBT LIMIT TO ONE YEAR ONLY
IF PRESIDENT OBAMA AGREES TO 1
TRILLION IN SPENDING CUTS FROM
GOVERNMENT PROGRAMS LIKE
MEDICARE.
>>> THE MOST DETAILS REPORT ON
THE BENGHAZI TERROR ATTACK WILL
BE RELEASED TODAY THE ATTACK
LEFT FOUR AMERICANS DEAD.
THE INDEPENDENT ADVISORY REVIEW
BOARD WILL DELIVER ITS
ASSESSMENT TO THE STATE
DEPARTMENT.
CONGRESS WILL SEE IT FOR A
CLASSIFIED BRIEFING WEDNESDAY.
THE STATE DEPARTMENT IS MAKING
RECOMMENDATIONS ON SECURITY
IMPROVEMENTS.
HILLARY CLINTON ORDERED THE
REVIEW.
SHE IS NOT EXPECT TO DO TESTIFY
ON CONGRESSIONAL HEARINGS.
THE PATRIOTS WAS A TOUCHING
TRIBUTE TO THE VICTIMS OF NEW
TOWN CONNECTICUT TRAGEDY.
26 WHITE FLARES WENT INTO THE
SKY DURING A MOMENT OF SILENCE.
THE PATRIOTS ALSO PLEDGING
25,000 TO HELP VICTIM'S
FAMILIES.
ROBERT CRAFT OWNS A BOX MAKING
FACTORY LESS THAN ONE MILE FROM
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE IN ZONE MILITIA WHO FIRE
INTO THE AIR EACH TIME THE TEAM
SCORES THEY REMAIN SILENT TO
HONOR THE VICTIMS.
THE TEAMS ACROSS THE LEAGUE ALSO
PAY TRIBUTE TO THE VICTIM.
THAT IS YOUR 5@5:00.
>>> IT IS TIME NOW FOR YOUR
FIRST DEGREE WEATHER UPDATE WITH
MARIA MOLINA.
TRACKING TWO STORMS ONE IN THE
EAST AND ONE IN THE WEST.
A STORM ACROSS NORTHWEST THAT IS
PRODUCING BLIZZARD CONDITIONS WE
HAVE BLIZZARD WARNINGS IN EFFECT
ACROSS THE BIG CHUNK OF THE WEST
AROUND WASHINGTON AND OTHER GONE
AND IDAHO.
ALSO WINTER STORM WARNINGS OUT
THERE.
COOL SIDE ACROSS PORTIONS OF THE
MIDWEST IT IS DECEMBER NOW.
20 OVER IN MINNEAPOLIS 21 RAPID
CITY.
ON THE EASTERN COAST WE ARE
SEEING TEMPERATURES IN THE 50s.
HIGH TEMPERATURES WON'T BE
WARMING UP A WHOLE LOT ACROSS
CAROLINAS INTO GEORGIA.
TEMPERATURES IN THE LOW 60s.
46 WILL BE THE HIGH TEMPERATURE
IN NEW YORK CITY AND OUT WEST.
WE HAVE TEMPERATURES IN THE 30s
AND 40s ACROSS PARTS OF OREGON
AND THE ROCKIES.
THEY WILL BE PRODUCING HE SHALL
-- IRRESPONSIBILISSUES ACROSS Y
WILL BE WARMING UP WE WILL SEE
SOME OF THE STORMS WILL PRODUCE
SEVERE WEATHER.
VERY UNUSUAL TO BE SEEING THIS
ACTIVITY DURING THE MONTH OF
DECEMBER.
WE HAVE HAD SNOW COMING DOWN
ACROSS PORTIONS OF NEW HAMPSHIRE
AND VERMONT AND THE STATE OF
MAINE.
YOU COULD SEE ACCUMULATIONS OVER
8 INCHES OF SNOW OVER HIGHER
ELEVATIONS OF NEW ENGLAND ACHLT
CROSS THE SOUTH SHOWERS AND
STORMS ALREADY FIRED UP.
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT BLIZZARD
CONDITIONS POSSIBLE.
WE HAVE A NUMBER OF WINTER
ADVISORIES HIGH WINDS WATCHES
AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT.
RAIN COMING DOWN ON THE COAST
AND PLEASE BE SAFE EVERYONE.
>> MARIA MOLINA.
IT IS 10 AFTER THE HOUR.
LAWMAKERS DON'T HAVE A DEAL ON
THE IFS HE CAL CLIFFME-- FISCAL.
YOU COULD BE WAITING LONGER FOR
YOUR TAX REFUND.
>> PLUS THE FOUNDER OF AMERICA'S
LARGEST FOOD CHAIN WANTS TO TAKE
THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT TO COURT
OVER THE HEALTHCARE LAWS
CONTRACEPTION MANDATE.
OO
OR YOU CAN GET OUT THERE
AND ACTUALLY LIKE SOMETHING.
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
as part
of a heart healthy diet.
That's true.
...But you still have to go
to the gym.
♪ The one and only, Cheerios
>> THE FUNERALS WILL BE HELD
LATER TODAY FOR TWO VICTIMS OF
FRIES SCHOOL SHOOTLING.
ONE OF THE VICTIMS JUST TURNED 6
LAST MONTH.
WE HAVE THE LATHES.
-- LATEST.
>> THE FIRST OF THESE FUNERALS
BEGIN LATER AT 1:00 P.M. THIS
AFTERNOON IN NEW TOWN
CONNECTICUT HERE THIS MORNING.
A 6-YEAR-OLD YOUNG JEWISH BOY
WHO WAS KILLED FRIDAY MORNING IN
THIS UNTHINKABLE MASSACRE WILL
BE LAID TO REST IT WAS QUOTED
SAYING HE WAS A GORGEOUS,
GORGEOUS BOY AND HE COULD REALLY
GET WHAT HE WANTED BY BATTING
THOSE LONG EYE LASHES AND
LOOKING AT YOU WITH THOSE BIG
BLUE EYES.
YOU REALLY COULDN'T SAY NO TO
HIM.
ALSO 6-YEAR-OLD JACK PIN CO ALSO
KILLED THAT MORNING.
A HUGE GIANTS FAN ACTUALLY.
ONE OF HIS POTENTIAL DREAMS
FULFILLED AFTER HIS DEATH AS
PLAYER VICTOR CRUISE WROTE HIS
NAME ON HIS SHOES IN HONOR OF
THAT YOUNG BOY.
I ATTENDED A CHURCH SERVICE AT A
LUTHERAN CHURCH SUNDAY MORNING
AND HEARD THAT PASTOR SPEAK
ABOUT JACK PINTO.
THAT PARTICULAR CHURCH WILL BE
HOLDING HIS FUNERAL LATER TODAY
ON THAT LUTHERAN CHURCH.
JOAQUIN TOE DID NOT ATTEND THAT
CHURCH WAS NOT A CHURCH GOING
FAMILY BUT THE PASTOR SAID HE
WAS BAPTIZED AS SOMETHING THE
GRANDPARENTS SOUGHT TO DO.
>> NOW TO STORIES YOU CAN BANK
ON THIS MORNING.
IF WE GO OVER THE FISCAL CLIFF,
WE COULD BE WAITING ALONG LONGER
FOR YOUR TAX REFUND.
LAUREN SIMONETTI IS HERE WITH
WHAT THAT MEANS.
>> IF THE FISCAL CLIFF DEAL IS
NOT REACHED BY THE END OF THE
YEAR TAX REFUND CHECKS MAY GET
DELAYED INTO THE SECOND QUARTER.
FILERS WOULDN'T GET TO COMPLETE
THEIR RETURNS UNTIL MARCH IF NOT
LATER.
IT PUTS 2,826 DOLLARS PER TAX
FILER.
SO MANY AMERICANS DE FENTD ON
THEIR REFINANCED CHECK AND DE
INVEST THAT MONEY BACK INTO THE
ECONOMY.
NOT TO MENTION OUR PAYCHECKS
WILL BE GETTING SMALLER AFTER
THE AUTOMATIC END OF THE YEAR
PAYROLL TAX HOLIDAY GOES AWAY
AND TAX RAKES FOR HIGH INCOME
EARNERS.
ALL OF THIS PUTS THE ECONOMY
BACK INTO THE RECESSION.
>> SPECIFICALLY MORE PEOPLE
MOVING OUT THAN MOVING IN.
>> HASN'T HAPPENED IN A REALLY
LONG TIME.
THE REASON IS CALIFORNIA MIGHT
BE PRETTY WITH GOOD WEATHER BUT
IT'S REALLY EXPENSIVE TO LIVE
THERE.
UNEMPLOYMENT IS HIGH AND
POPULATION IS DENSE.
>>> MANY IMGRANMIGRANTS IN MEFR
ARE RETURN TO GO MEXICO.
>> HOLIDAY CHRISTMAS SHOPPING WE
MAY BE DEPENDING ON THE
OVERNIGHT DELIVERY.
A LOT OF FOLKS AREN'T DOING
THAT.
>> SAME DAY SHIPPING IS A TREND
RIGHT NOW NOT REALLY CATCHING ON
BUT IT IS A WAY RETAILERS ARE
TRYING TO GET BUSINESS.
IT REALLY IS NOT POPULAR IN THE
END THE REASON IS THE COST.
THEY RETURN THE ITEMS TO THE
SCORE THEY ARE NOT PAYING FOR
THIS INSTANT GRATIFICATION.
WAL-MART TESTED IT IN OCTOBER.
AMAZON LAUNCHED IT BACK IN 20009
THEY HAVE IT IN TEN MARKETS AND
eBAY TESTING IT IN SAN FRANCISCO
AND NEW YORK.
>> SAME DAY, NOT OVERNIGHT.
>> THE TEST COULD COME AT THE
END OF CHRISTMAS.
>> PEOPLE WILL BE VERY LAST
MINUTE THIS YEAR.
MYSELF INCLUDED.
THOUGHT I WAS DONE.
>> APPRECIATE IT.
>>> THE TIME NOW IS 18 AFTER THE
TOP OF THE HOUR.
HIS SMALL BUSINESS WAS DESTROYED
BY A VIOLENT MOB OF UNION
PROTESTORS.
NOW HE IS GETTING SOME HELP
BOUNCING BACK.
OUR COVERAGE OF THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT.
NEXT EVERYONE IS ASKING WHY THIS
HAPPENED.
IS IT THE PRODUCT OF A CHANGING
CULTURE?
SCHOOL COUNSELOR AND PSYCHO
THERAPIST JOINS US UP NEXT.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS STEVE.
HE LOVES RISK.
BUT WHETHER
HE'S CLIMBING EVEREST,
SCUBA DIVING THE
GREAT BARRIER REEF WITH SHARKS,
OR JUMPING INTO THE MARKE
HE GOES WITH PEOPLE HE TRUSTS,
WHICH IS WHY HE TRADES
WITH A COMPANY
THAT DOESN'T NICKEL AND DIME
HIM WITH HIDDEN FEES.
SO HE CAN WORRY
ABOUT OTHER THINGS,
LIKE WHAT THE MARKET IS DOING
AND BEING READY,
NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENS,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE,
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
[ engine revs ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THE MERCEDES-BENZ WINTER EVENT
IS BACK,
WITH THE PERFECT VEHICLE
THAT'S JUST RIGHT FOR YOU,
NO MATTER WHICH LIST YOU'RE ON.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
C250 FOR $349 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
This Bible changed the world.
I'm Kirk Cameron. Four Hundred
years ago
our forefathers risked their
lives to bring this Bible to the
shores of America.
Because it contained
the principals for economic
liberty,
political liberty and religious
freedom. The 1599 Geneva Bible.
It was the first
complete english
translation, complete with
chapters,
numbered verses and 300,000
utterly unique study notes.
It actually came out
before the King James
Version and because the
government didn't authorize it,
it was outlawed. But it was a
Bible by the people,
for the people, the book
that built America.
And now for the first time
in 400 years it's
available again in a bea
leather edition. I have one,
I want you to have yours too.
Please visit GenevaBible.com
and get your copy
of this rare and historic
version of God's Word today.
Thank you and may God bless you.
>> WELCOME BACK.
IT IS 21 MINUTES AFTER THE TOP
OF THE HOUR.
SYRIAN VICE PRESIDENT SAID THE
GOVERNMENT AND THE REBELS ARE
LOSING THE WAR.
HE SAID NEITHER SIDE CAN WIN
MILITARILY.
AFTER 21 MONTHS OF FIGHTING
INSTEAD HE SUGGESTS ENDING THE
VIOLENCE AND CREATING A UNIFIED
GOVERNMENT.
THE FOUNDER OF DOMINO'S PIZZA
JOINING THE FIGHT AGAINST OBAMA
CARE.
HE IS SUING THE LOCAL GOVERNMENT
FOREMAN DATES.
MONAHAN A DEVOUT CATHOLIC SAYS
THE LAW RVIOLATES HIS RIGHTS.
>> AS WE REMEMBER THE VICTIMS OF
THE CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTING
WE ARE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE
SHOOTER THERE WERE CLAIMS HE HAD
A PERSONALITY DISORDER POSSIBLY
ASPERGER'S SYNDROME.
HE TALKED ABOUT LACK OF SUPPORT
IN FAMILIES WITH HEALTH
PROBLEMS.
>> I WOULD GO TO THE
MASSACHUSETTS GENERAL HOSPITAL
STATE HOSPITALS THEY WERE IN
DANGER OF THEMSELVES TO OTHERS.
IT HAS BECOME MUCH HARDER TO DO.
NOT SOMETHING ANY PSYCHIATRIST
EVER DOES LIGHTLY.
THE DILEMMA FOR A PARENT IS YOU
ARE IN THESE TERRIBLE
RELATIONSHIPS BECAUSE OF THE
RISE OF CIVIL LIBERTIES AND
BASED ON WHAT WE HAD IN THE 50s
OF THE ABUSE OF INCARCERATION OF
THE MENTALLY ILL.
IT BECOMES IMPOSSIBLE.
>> SO WHAT ARE FAMILIES TO DO?
LET'S ASK PSYCHO THERAPIST AND
SCHOOL COUNSELOR.
>> WE ARE TALKING ABOUT A
POSSIBLE ASPERGER'S ANGLE HERE.
THERE'S NO EVIDENCE --
>> I HAVE GOTTEN E-MAILS FROM
PEOPLE ABOUT THAT.
THERE IS NO EVIDENCE THAT
SOMEBODY WITH ASPERGER'S HAS
VIOLENT BEHAVIORS.
THEY MIGHT HAVE SOCIAL
AWKWARDNESS BUT TO LINK THE TWO
IS PREMATURE.
>>> GETTING BACK TO THE ROOT
CAUSES OF THIS TYPE OF THING.
A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE POINTING TO
THE CHANGING CULTURE.
THE SHOOTER PLAYED VIOLENT VIDEO
GAMES.
THESE GAMES DO NOT WANT TO HEAR
ANY LINK BETWEEN TWOT.
>> I TALK TO PARENTS ABOUT THIS
ALL OF THE TIME.
I HAVE YOUNG KIDS AND I SEE MY
KID'S FRIENDS PLAYING THESE
VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES.
NOTHING I WOULD DO WITH MY KIDS.
WE WANT TO KEEP OUR KIDS, WE
WANT TO MAINTAIN THE KID'S
INNOCENCE.
THEY DON'T NEED TO BE HE CAN
POSED TO VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES.
PART OF THE PROBLEM PARENTS
BECOME DESENSITIZED.
WELL, JOHNNY HAS THIS GAME, SARA
HAS THIS GAME.
SUDDENLY IT IS NOT TOO BIG OF A
PROBLEM.
>> YOU HEAR DESENSITIZED.
PEOPLE WATCH ENOUGH VIOLENCE AND
ALL OF A SUDDEN THEY BECOME NUMB
TO THE THOUGHT OF IT.
>> WHATEVER YOU ARE PUMPING INTO
YOUR SUBCONSCIOUS MIND BECOMES A
REALITY.
IF YOU ARE DOING STUFF OR
ENGAGED IN AN ACTIVITY OVER AND
OVER AGAIN YOUR BRAIN WILL
CREATE NEUROPATHWAYS CONSISTENT
WITH THAT.
YOU COULD BECOME COMPLETELY
DESENSITIZED TO VIOLENT VIDEO
GAMES AND ALMOST BECOME A
KILLER.
THINK OF ALL OF THESE THINGS
THAT HAVE BEEN HAPPENING OVER
THE LAST SEVERAL YEARS.
THERE HAS TO BE A CONNECTION
THERE.
>> PEOPLE WOULD SAY THERE'S
PLENTY OF PEOPLE WHO WATCH THE
MOVIES.
THERE ARE VULNERABILITIES THERE.
LET'S GET TO THAT.
LACK OF FAMILY TIME YOU SAY ONE
OF THE KEYS.
>> THIS IS SLG I TALK TO
FAMILIES ABOUT ALL OF THE TIME.
I GIVE TALKS ALL OF THE TIME.
PEOPLE MAY THEY THEY ARE VL
QUALITY TIME I LOOK AT FAMILIES
BEING INDIVIDUALS LIVING UNDER
THE SAME ROOF.
DADS ON THE CELL PHONES MOM
WATCHING TELEVISION JOHN PLAY
AGO VIDEO GAME THE OTHER MAY BE
LISTENING TO HER iPOD.
TEXTING.
WE HAVE INDIVIDUAL COMPLETELY
DISTRACTED AND NOT ENGAGED NOT
LIVING TOGETHER AS FAMILIES.
>> FAMILY DINNER.
>> SOMETHING THAT IS IMPORTANT
TO ME.
IT'S A LOST ART IN OUR COUNTRY
TANKS CRITICAL FAMILIES TAKE THE
TIME TO SIT DOWN MAKE A
COMMITMENT HAVE MEALS TOGETHER
AND KEEP THE DISTRACTIONS AWAY.
>> NO GADGETS AT DINNER.
>>> THE TIME RIGHT NOW 26 AFTER
THE HOUR.
STILL TO COME IT IS THEIR JOB TO
PROTECT EMPLOYEES AGAINST UNFAIR
UNION PRACTICES, BUT A NEW
REPORT SAYS THE NLRB WAS LOOKING
AFTER THE UNION.
IN A STRI
IN A VICTORY CELEBRATION GOES
WRONG WITH FANS SPILLING ON TO
THE FOOTBALL FIELD.
WE WILL HAVE THAT STORY.
N.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
You know how painful heartburn
can be.
For fast, long lasting relief,
use doctor recommended
Gaviscon®.
Only Gaviscon® forms a
protective barrier that helps
block stomach acid from
splashing up-
relieving the pain quickly.
Try fast, long lasting
Gaviscon®.
>> THE NATION AND THE WORLD
GRIEVING FROM THE TRAGEDY IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
NEW YORK CITY'S TIMES SQUARE
FULL OF PEOPLE HOLDING OCCUPY
CANDLES.
PEOPLE GATHERING FOR A VIGIL
OUTSIDE OF THE WHITE HOUSE IN
WASHINGTON, D.C.
>> AND A LOOK AT FLOWERS AND
TOYS ALONG THE STREETS OF MOSCOW
OUTSIDE THE U.S. EMBASSY AND RIO
DE JANEIRO CROSSES LINING THE
BEACH MOURNERS LAYING FLOWERS IN
THE SAND.
AFFECTS EVERYONE AROUND THE
WHOLE WORLD.
>> WELCOME BACK TO FOX AND
FRIENDS FIRST.
I AM HEATHER CHILDERS.
>> I AM PATTI ANN BROWNE.
THE FIRST FUNERALS WILL BE HELD
TODAY FOR TWO OF THE VICTIMS.
LAST NIGHT THE COMMUNITY CAME
TOGETHER IN PRAYER.
(APPLAUSE)
>> A STANDING OVATION FOR
NEWTOWN'S FIRST RESPONDERS AND
THEN PRESIDENT OBAMA WHO OFFERED
WORDS OF COMFORT AND SUPPORT.
PETER DOOCY JOINS US LIVE FROM
NEW TOWN WITH MORE.
PETER?
>> HEATHER, PRESIDENT OBAMA CAME
TO NEWTOWN JUST AFTER THEY
EXPERIENCED THE INITIAL SHOCK OF
WHAT HAPPENED ON FRIDAY.
JUST BEFORE THEY MUST START
DEALING WITH THE FACT HERE
STARTING TODAY THEY WILL NEED TO
BURY 20 CHILD SIZED COFFINS.
>> I AM VERY MINDFUL THAT MERE
WORDS CANNOT MATCH THE DEPTHS OF
YOUR SORROW.
NOR CAN THEY HEEL YOUR WOUNDED
HEARTS.
I CAN ONLY HOPE IT HELPS FOR YOU
TO KNOW THAT YOU ARE NOT ALONE
IN YOUR GRIEF.
THAT OUR WORLD, TOO, HAS BEEN
TORN APART.
ALL ACROSS THIS LAND OF OURS WE
HAVE WEPT WITH YOU.
WE HOLD OUR CHILDREN TIGHT.
>> PERIOR TO GIVING THAT NATIONL
ADDRESS PRESIDENT OBAMA MET WITH
THE FAMILIES OF THOSE WHO WERE
KILLED FRIDAY.
DAWN MOCH SPRUNG'S DAUGHTER
TWEETED MY MOM WOULD BE SO PROUD
TO SEE PRESIDENT OBAMA HOLDING
HER GRANDDAUGHTER BUT NOT AS
PROUD AS I AM OF HER.
>> 6-YEAR-OLD EMILIE PARKER'S
FAMILY POSTED A FEW PICTURES
WITH PRESIDENT OBAMA AS WELL.
SOME ARE SOMBER BUT SOMEHOW THE
DEVASTATED FAMILY MANAGED TO
SMILE.
>> ADAM LANZA FIRED HUNDREDS OF
ROUNDS INSIDE SANDY HOOK EL EM
TRY SCHOOL.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID HE IS GOING
TO DO WHATEVER HE CAN AS
PRESIDENT TO MAKE SURE WHAT
HAPPENED ON FRIDAY NEVER HAPPENS
GENIE WHERE.
>> CAN WE HONESTLY SAY WE ARE
DOING ENOUGH TO KEEP OUR
CHILDREN, ALL OF THEM SAFE FROM
HARM?
CAN WE CLAIM AS A NATION THAT WE
ARE ALL TOGETHER THERE, LETTING
THEM KNOW THEY ARE LOED AND
TEACHING THEM TO LOVE IN RETURN?
CAN WE SAY THAT WE ARE TRULY
DOING ENOUGH TO GIVE ALL THE
CHILDREN OF THIS COUNTRY THE
CHANCE THEY DESERVE TO LIVE OUT
THEIR LIVES IN HAPPINESS AND
WITH PURPOSE?
I HAVE BEEN REFLECTING ON THIS
THE LAST FEW DAYS, AND IF WE ARE
HONEST WITH OURSELVES, THE
ANSWER IS NO.
>>> A GROUP OF TOWNS PEOPLE
GATHERED IN A POPULAR RESTAURANT
IN NEWTOWN IN COMPLETE SILENCE.
I ASKED ONE MAN WHAT HE THOUGHT
ABOUT THE PRESIDENT'S REMARKS
ABOUT THAT CALM ACTION.
HE THOUGHT IT WAS GREAT JUS
HOPE PRESIDENT OBAMA FOLLOWS
THROUGH ON THAT PROMISE TO ACT
THE BIG THINGS.
THAT IS THE QUESTION.
PETER DOOCY, WHAT CAN A NATION
DO TO PREVENT SUCH HORROR.
TO YOUING LOU ZIADER IS LIVE
TOFOR
US ON MAUSHING CON.
THAT WILL WILL BE ANOTHER GUT
WRENCHING DAY.
IN A MEMORIAL SERVICE THE
PRESIDENT PROMISED TO DO MORE TO
PROTECT THE NATION'S CHILDREN.
HE WALKED ON STAGE AFTER MEETING
WITH THE FAMILIES OF THE
YOUNGEST VICTIMS OF THIS ATTACK.
HE ASKED WHETHER THE NATION WAS
DOING ENOUGH TO PROTECT THE
CHILDREN.
THE PRESIDENT DIDN'T SAY WHAT
KIND OF CHANGE HE WOULD ADVOCATE
EVEN SOME OF HIS SUPPORTERS SAY
HE NEEDS TO PUSH FOR SOMETHING
COMPREHENSIBLE.
I HAVE WANTED TO SIT DOWN AND
CALMLY DISCUSS ALL OF THE
OPTIONS.
WE NEED TO DO THIS AS A NATION.
THAT'S THE ONLY WAY WE CAN MOVE
FORWARD AND MAKE SURE THERE'S A
LESSON TO BE LEARNED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> THERE ARE MANY ADDITIONAL
CALLS FOR GUN LEGISLATION THAT
WILL PLAY OUT.
MANY ROLES COULD COMPLICATE A
SCENARIO INVOLVING NOT JUST GUNS
BUT A SKEWER WHO MAY HAVE BEEN
TRAVELING.
WE NEED TO START WITH THE
FAMILIAR IF HE CAN INDICATIONS
IT WAS A SOCIAL INTERACTION
BETWEEN VIOLENCE, THE REALISM
YOU FI
FUND IN GAINS AND MOVIES.
AREN'T ABLE TO MENTALLY TAKE
THAT TRANSITION.
WE LOOK AT THE FAMILY,
COMMUNITIES AND CHURCHES AM.
THE RESULT OF TALKS STORMING A
NATIONAL COMMISSION TO ALL
ACCESS OF THESE SILENT TESTS.
>> THANK YOU.
DOUG.
THANK YOU.
>> NOW FOR YOUR # 5595:30.
KWLOEFR NIGHT TWO POLICE
STATIONS IN BENGHAZI LIBYA WERE
TARGETED IN WHAT APPEARS TO HAVE
BEEN SIMULTANEOUS ATTACKED.
THE MALL GLASS BENT OFF TOE TER
DAMAGING A WALL, NO INJURIES AT
EITHER SITE.
IT IS SUPPOSED TO PROTECT THEM
FROM UNPLAYER UNION OR MANAGE AM
PROCESSES.
THEY CLAIM THE NATIONAL LABOR
RELATIONS BOARD HAS BECOME A
BIASSED AT CAT BETWEEN THE
GENERAL PORTION AND NONUNION
GOING PLANS.
THE AGENCY SAID IT WOULD REVIEW
THE REPORT.
>>> AN UPDATE ON A STORY WE HAVE
BEEN FOLLOWING.
LAST WEEK TWOELD YOU ABOUT
CLINTON FROM LANSING MICHIGAN.
UNION WORKERS DESTROYED THE
FAMOUS HOT DOG CART DURING
VIOLENT RIGHT TO WORK PROTESTS.
IN RESPONSE DONATED # MORE THAN
33,000 DOLLARS.
SUPPLIES FOR HIS BUSINESS.
>> THE WINNER OF TIMES TERNE OF
THE PEER.
THE EVENER IS KIM I DON'T THINK
ILL.
THEY RECEIVED 5.6 MILLION VOTES
BECAUSE THE INTERNET PACKED THE
WHOLE THING.
THEY MANIPULATED OR MANAGED TO
NAN NIP LATE THE WHOLE FOR THE
SECOND TIME IN.
WP WEDNESDAY.
>>> KATE MILLED DONE DEDUCTIONS
OF CAME BRAJ.
SHE PRESENTED TWO OF THE AWARDS.
SHE WANT RECENTLY HOSPITALIZED
DURING A MORNING RICK YS GOING
OHM AFTER 45 MINUTES.
THAT'S YOUR 5@5:30.
>> BEFORE YOU LEIGH THE HOUSE
THIS MORNING IT'S TIME TO GET
THE WEATHER BEG WEATHER UPDATE.
YOU ARE TRACKING TWO
THUNDERSTORMS ONE UT EAST AND
WON LEFT.
WASHINGTON INTO PART OF WYOMING
ANT BLIZZARD PORTIONS IN EFFECT.
YOU ARE NOT SEEING ADDITIONAL
SNOWFALL ACCUMULATIONS.
DIG CAN'T WIND WILL BE CAUSING
WHITE HOUSE CONDITIONS GUSTING
TO OVER 30, 40 MILES PER HOUR
WEST.
OTHERWISE ACROSS THE EAST IT
WILL BE A LITTLE REMINDER.
THROUGH GEORGIA INTO TARTS OF
TENNESSEE LARGE HAIL.
ISOLATED TORN COULD IS IF YOU
LIVE THERE WE HAVE SNOW COPYING
DOWN ACROSS PORTIONS OF VERMONT.
MAINE, HEYER PORTION OF WILL YOU
ENGLAND.
COULD PICK UP OVER 6 OVER THE
SNOW N. MINUTE MID ATLANTIC SIT
OFFING PORTS OF THE TON TREE.
66 DALLAS SAN ANTONIO.
>>> THE TIME NOW IS 39 AFTER THE
TOP OF THE HOUR.
COMING UP THERE'S SOME KIND OF
MOVEMENT ON THE FISCAL CLIFF
TALKS.
IT MY MOTT BE GOOD FOR YOUR
MOWN.
>> A SOLDIER REUNITED WITH HIS
FAMILY JUST IN TIME TO WELCOME
THE NEWEST MEMBER.
THAT STORY KEY COMING UP.
>> AFTER WEEKS OF A DEAD LOOK
THERE SEEMS TOCK SOME MOVEMENT
ON THE FISCAL CLIFF.
HERE TO BREAK DOWN NEGOTIATIONS
IS DIANE MACEDO.
>> LOOKS LIKE REPUBLICAN HOUSE
SPEAKER BOEHNER IS CLOSER TO THE
KEY DEMANDS TO AVERT TAX HIKES
AND SPENDING CUTS WHICH WIARE S
TO TAKE EFFECT IN THE START OF
THE NEW YEAR.
HE PROPOSED ALLOWING TAX RATES
TO GO UP FOR ANY ONE MAKING
$1 MILLION A YEAR.
THAT'S WITH THE PRESIDENT'S
DESIRE FAX CUTS EXPIRE FOR ANY
ONE MAKING 250,000 A YEAR.
BOEHNER INCREASED THE FIGURE FOR
TOTAL TAX REVENUE FOR
$1 TRILLION.
THE SPEAKER ALSO CONDITIONED HIS
OFFER ON THE PRESIDENT AGREEING
TO 1 TRILLION 234 SPENDING CUTS.
MANY REPUBLICAN LAWMAKERS WANT
TO RAISE THE ELIGIBILITY AGE OR
FED CARE TO 67 TO 55.
A MAJOR BLOCK OF CONGRESSIONAL
THEY CAN EXCEPT.
THE OTHER PEACE THE UCHL TRERP
TREASURY.
WILL AHOSPITAL THIS BUT NOT
UNTIL MID FEBRUARY.
NO CUTS NO DEBT LIMIT INCREASE.
>>> EXPECT LAWMAKERS TO PICK UP
THE PACE THIS WEEK.
HOUSE REPUBLICANS ARE PREPARING
FOR A POSSIBLE WEEKEND SESSION
SPECIFICALLY THE TRAVEL PLANS.
THEY MAY BE HEADING DO A GROUND
STORM.
>> SIRN SIMONETTI.
HE CELEBRATE HIS TEAMS WIN WITH
FANS WHEN, IT IS COMING, ALL OF
A SUDDEN DIN THE GUA-- SUDDEN T
GUARDRAIL THEY ARE MEETING ON
COLLAPSES.
YOU CAN SEE THE PEOPLE FALLING
ON TO THE FIELD.
NO WORD YET IF ANY OF THEM WERE
INJURED.
JERRY RETURNS HOME FROM
AFGHANISTAN JUST IN TIME FOR THE
NEWEST ADDITION TO THE FAMILY.
SURPRISING FIRST HIS TWO LITTLE
GIRLS IN THEIR PINK BOWS WHO HE
HASN'T SEN SINCE SEPTEMBER.
THE RED CROSS ARRANGED FOR THE
EMERGENCY FLIGHT HOME WHEN HIS
WIFE WENT INTO LABOR.
WE NEEDED THAT NICE STORY TODAY.
>>> 46 AFTER THE HOUR.
STILL TO COME AS KIDS HEAD BACK
TO SCHOOL FOR THE FIRST TIME
SINCE THE CONNECTICUT SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
WHAT ADVICE.
>> LET'S CHECK IN WITH STOOE
DOOCY TO SEE WHAT'S COMING UP ON
"FOX & FRIENDS."
>> ANOTHER SPECIAL ED KIGS WE
ARE GOING TO HAVE LIVE COVERAGE
FROM NEWTOWN IN CONNECTICUT.
THE LATEST ON WHAT THE PRESIDENT
SAID LAST NIGHT.
TWO LITTLE BYES WILL BE ARRESTED
IN OVERNIGHT DEVELOPMENTS.
OO
This Bible changed the world.
I'm Kirk Cameron. Four Hundred
years ago
our forefathers risked their
lives to bring this Bible to the
shores of America.
Because it contained
the principals for economic
liberty,
political liberty and religious
freedom. The 1599 Geneva Bible.
It was the first
complete english
translation, complete with
chapters,
numbered verses and 300,000
utterly unique study notes.
It actually came out
before the King James
Version and because the
government didn't authorize it,
it was outlawed. But it was a
Bible by the people,
for the people, the book
that built America.
And now for the first time
in 400 years it's
available again in a beautiful
leather edition. I have one,
I want you to have yours too.
Please visit GenevaBible.com
and get your copy
of this rare and historic
version of God's Word today.
Thank you and may God bless you.
>> THE SHOOTING INVESTIGATION
YESTERDAY THEY RELEASE DETAILS.
NYW'S ROBERT MOSES IS LIVE IN
NEWTOWN WITH DETAILS.
>>> GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
GOOD MORNING EVERYONE.
WE ARE STANDING IN TREADWELL
PARK.
THIS IS WHERE POLICE HAVE BEEN
GIVING US DAILY BRIEFINGS.
WE ARE EXPECTING TO HEAR FROM
STATE POLICE AGAIN A LITTLE
LATER ON THIS MORNING AT 9:00.
STILL POLICE SAY THEY ARE WEEKS
AWAY FROM DETERMINING WHAT LED
THIS SHOOTER TO GO ON THIS
RAMPAGE.
POLICE CONFIRM THE SHOOTER'S
NAME ADAM LANZA.
HE SHOT HIS MOTHER NANCY IN
NEWTOWN ON FRIDAY THEN DROVE TO
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND
FORCED HIS WAY INTO THE SCHOOL.
HE WAS CARRYING THREE WEAPONS
WITH HIM ALL OF THEM LEGALLY
REGISTERED TO HIS MOTHER.
POLICE SAY HE DID THE BULK OF
HIS SHOOTING WITH A BUSHMASTER
AR 15 ASSAULT WEAPONS.
IT INFLICTS MAXIMUM DAMAGE IT IS
USED IN THE MILITARY.
POLICE SAY HE SHOT ALL OF HIS
VICTIMS MULTIPLE TIMES THEN HE
TOOK HIS OWN LIFE WITH ONE OF
THE TWO HAND GUNS HE CARRIES.
>>> ALL WEAPONS HAD MULTIPLE
MAGAZINES AND ADDITIONAL
AMMUNITION.
THE FOURTH WEAPONRY COVERED WAS
A SHOT GUN THAT WAS RECOVERED
FROM THE SUSPECT'S VEHICLE AS IT
WAS PARKED OUTSIDE OF THE
SCHOOL.
>> PERHAPS THE MOST TERRIFYING
PART OF THE STORY IS THE FACT
THAT THERE WERE HUNDREDS OF
BULLETS AS WELL AS UNSPENT
MAGAZINES FOUND NEAR HIS BODY
INSIDE THE SCHOOL LEADING
AUTHORITIES TO BELIEF HAD POLICE
NOT ARRIVED WHEN THEY DID THE
SHOOTING AS HORRIBLE AS IT WAS
COULD HAVE BEEN EVEN WORSE.
THAT IS THE LATEST LIVE FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT THIS
MORNING.
PATTI ANN, BACK TO YOU.
>>> THANK YOU.
>> IT'S A TREMENDOUS CHALLENGE
FOR SCHOOL OFFICIALS, BECAUSE
SCHOOL CAMPUSES ARE NOT DESIGNED
TO BE FORTRESSES TO BE DEFENDED.
THEY ARE PLACES OF LEARNING.
IF YOU HAVE A ARMED PERSON TINT
ON GETTING ON TO THE CAMPUS THEY
WILL USE WHATEVER MEANS
NECESSARY.
THIS IS NOT AN UNCOMMON
SITUATION WHERE THEY DEFEAT SOME
OF THE BEST SYSTEMS THAT ARE IN
PLACE.
>>> THAT WAS RONALD STEVENS THE
DIRECTOR OF THE NATIONAL SCHOOL
SAFETY CENTER OUTLINING SOME OF
THE CHALLENGES THAT SCHOOLS FACE
KEEPING CHILDREN SAFE.
THIS AS WE LEARN THAT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENT TRE SCHOOL INSTALLED NEW
SECURITY MEASURES THAT CAN
PROTECT AND DEFEND AGAINST SUCH
A HORRIFIC ACT OF VIOLENCE.
CAN YOU, THAT IS THE QUESTION
PARENTS ARE ASKING.
STEVEN ROGERS JOINS US NOW.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
>> YOU ARE WELCOME.
>> SCHOOLS ARE NOT FORTRESSES TO
BE DEFENDED.
HERE'S NOT WHAT THEY ARE
SUPPOSED TO BE.
THIS SCHOOL HASANDY HOOK HAVE
TAKEN ALL OF THE PRECAUTIONS
THEY NEEDED TO.
>> NOTHING COULD STOP HIM FROM
GOING INTO THE GOIBUILDING AND
DOING WHAT HE DID.
AFTER GOAT IN THE HEROICS OF THE
TEACHERS THE POLICE ALL OF THOSE
PEOPLE WHO SURVIVED PROTECTING
THOSE CHILDREN.
YOU COULD HAVE HAD METAL
DETECTORS.
THAT GUY WAS HELL BENT ON
GETTING IN THAT BUILDING TO DO
WHAT HE DID.
>> SCHOOLS ACROSS THE COUNTRY
HAVE UPPED SECURITY MEASURES.
TAKE A LOOK AT SOME OF THE
NUMBERS.
92 PERCENT OF SCHOOLS LOCK OR
MONITOR DOORS.
63 HERS USE ELECTRONIC EMERGENCY
NOTIFICATION SO THEY CAN LET
FAMILIES KNOW IF THERE IS
SOMETHING GOING ON.
THE TEACHERS LOCKING THE DOORS
MOVING THEM BACK HIDING THEM IN
CUB BOARDS AND BATHROOMS.
>> I LOOKED AT THE LOCK DOWN
POLICY IT WORKS.
THE TEACHERS IN PARTICULAR TAKE
FULL CONTROL OF THE SITUATION
HIGH HIDING CHILDREN BY GOING TO
THE BACK OF THE CLASSROOMS.
YOU CAN'T DO ENOUGH TO PROTECT
FROM A CRAZED PERSON.
99 PERCENT OF THE SCHOOL
DISTRICTS ACROSS THE NATION ARE
WELL PROTECTED WHEN IT COMES TO
LOCKING DOORS.
I AM AN ELECTED OFFICIAL IN MY
COMMUNITY.
WHEN I GO I AM ESCORTED I HAVE
TO SIGN IN.
THESE ARE PROCEDURES THAT HELP
PREVENT A NONCRAZED PERSON FROM
GOING IN ANDING COMMITTING THE
VIE LENGTHS.
>> WHAT SHOULD PARENTS BE ASKING
AT SCHOOLS IN TERMS OF SECURITY?
>> WHAT CAN WE DO TO HELP WHAT
CAN WE DO TO MAKE SUGGESTIONS.
SOME PARENTS CALLED ME OVER THE
WEEKEND.
I SAID LOOK, HUG YOUR CHILDREN,
PRAY FOR YOUR CHILDREN BE CLOSE
TO THEM.
ON FOX YOU ARE DOING GREAT WORK
IN HEIGHTENING AWARENESS OF WHAT
NEEDS TO BE DONE TO STOP THE
PROBLEM.
I HAVE HEARD IT THROUGH OUT THE
ENTIRE WEEKEND, LOVE YOUR
FAMILIES, GET TOGETHER WITH YOUR
FAMILIES AND TALK.
I AM IN LAW ENFORCEMENT I AM NOT
A PSYCHIATRIST.
THE 38 YEARS I HAVE BEEN IN LAW
ENFORCE.
THE CONNECTION TO VIOLENT GAMES
AND TELEVISION AND MOVIES, IT'S
TRUE.
PARENTS NEED TO STEP UP AND SAY
WE HAVE TO CONTROL THE VIOLENCE
IN OUR HOMES WORK WITH THE
POLICE AND TEACHERS.
WE USE THAT WORD EVERYONE SEEMS
TO BE AFRAID OF LOVE.
>>> THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
JOINING US.
55 AFTER THE TOP OF THE HOUR.
WE WILL BE RIGHT BACK.
TRY RUNNING FOUR.NING
A RESTAURANT IS HARD,
FORTUNATELY WE'VE GOT INK.
IT GIVES US 5X THE REWARDS
ON OUR INTERNET, PHONE
CHARGES AND CABLE,
PLUS AT OFFICE SUPPLY STORES.
.OUR BU
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
WE'VE EVER WANTED TO DO
AND INK HELPS US DO IT.
MAKE YOUR MARK
WITH INK FROM CHASE.
♪
AS WE SAY GOODBYE, A SOMBER
LOOK AT THE NAPES OF THE
TRAGIC VICTIMS WHO LOST THEIR
LIVES.
THEY ARE IN OUR THOUGHTS AND
PRAYERS.
THER IN OUR THOUGHTS AND
PRAYERS AND THE ENTIRE
COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN.
♪