>> Bill: WELCOME TO THE FOX
REPORT.
NOW THE DAY AFTER HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, A
COMMUNITY, AS YOU CAN IMAGINE,
ABSOLUTELY DEVASTATED BY A
HORRENDOUS ACT THAT SO MANY OF
US ARE JUST NOW COMING TO GRIPS
WITH.
IT COULD HAVE HAPPENED IN ANY
CORNER OF OUR COUNTRY AND NOW
PEOPLE ALL OVER THE COUNTRY,
FROM COAST TO COAST, OFFERING A
MESSAGES OF SUPPORT.
>> WE UNDERSTAND THE POWER OF
PRAYER AS WHAT IT IS.
WE KNOW THAT WE CAN INTERCEDE
FOR PEOPLE.
WE DON'T HAVE TO BE THERE.
WE CAN BE RIGHT HERE AND MAKE AN
IMPACT.
PEOPLE SAY E-MAIL TRAVELS FAST.
PRAYER TRAVELS FASTER.
>> I HOPE AND PRAY FOR THOSE
FAMILIES, FOR THAT TOWN, THAT
CITY, THAT STATE, THAT THEY CAN
SOMEHOW GET THROUGH.
>> I KEPT THINKING OVER AND OVER
AGAIN, THIS COULD BE MY KID.
THIS COULD BE MY KID.
AND I JUST FELT LIKE THERE IS
NOT MUCH I CAN DO FROM HERE
ACTION BUT I FELT LIKE I HAVE TO
SAY SOMETHING.
>> WE'RE SHOWING THAT WE -- THEY
HAVE OUR SUPPORT.
>> 1,000 MILES AWAY.
>> THE DISTANCE IS ALMOST
IRRELEVANT, THAT WE ARE ALL JUST
CHILDREN OF GOD AND WHEN A
GRIEVANCE LIKE THIS AND A
TRAGEDY LIKE THIS HITS, WE'RE
ALL ONE.
>> I DIDN'T KNOW THEM OR
ANYTHING, BUT MY HEART JUST GOES
OUT AND I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT
TO PRAY FOR THEM.
>> Bill: IT IS ANOTHER TOUGH
DAY.
AND GOOD EVENING YET AGAIN.
I'M BILL HEMMER LIVE NEAR THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
AT LAST HOUR, WE WERE GIVEN THE
NAMES OF THE 20 CHILDREN AND
WHEN YOU LOOK AT THIS LIST BORN
IN 2005 AND 2006, AGES SIX AND
SEVEN, AND YOU READ THE NAMES,
DANIEL AND CHARLOTTE AND
KATHERINE AND GRACE AND JACK,
AND CHASE AND DYLAN AND MADELINE
AND 12 OTHERS, RIPS YOUR HEART
OUT.
WE ARE BACK HERE TONIGHT TO
CONTINUE ON THE STORY WHERE THE
TEACHERS AND THE PARENTS AND THE
POLICE, EVERYONE IS LOOKING FOR
AN ANSWER AS TO WHY TONIGHT.
THIS NOW A DAY AFTER A GUNMAN
THOUSAND THAT SCHOOL AND SHOT 26
PEOPLE DEAD AND POLICE NOW
REVEALING THOSE VICTIMS.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER, ABOUT TWO
HOURS AGO, CONFIRMED ALL SIX
ADULTS WHO DIED WERE WOMEN.
AMONG THE 20 CHILDREN, EIGHT OF
THEM WERE BOYS.
12 WERE GIRLS.
ALL AGAIN BETWEEN THE AGES OF
SIX AND SEVEN.
ALL OF THEM WERE SHOT MORE THAN
ONE TIME.
>> I'VE BEEN AT THIS FOR A THIRD
OF A CENTURY.
MY SENSIBILITIES MAY NOT BE THE
AVERAGE MAN, BUT THIS PROBABLY
IS THE WORST I HAVE SEEN.
>> Bill: THAT WAS THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER WHO WAS BRIEFING
REPORTERS HERE JUST ABOUT 90
MINUTES AGO.
THERE IS A LOT MORE FROM HIS
BRIEFING HERE THAT TELLS US WHAT
HAS HAPPENED INSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
IT'S GRIPPING.
ONE OF THE GIRLS, SIX-YEAR-OLD
BY THE NAME OF EMILY PARKER,
ONLY MOMENTS AGO HER FATHER,
ROBBIE, HE MOVED THIS COMMUNITY
FROM THE WEST SIDE OF THE UNITED
STATES EIGHT MONTHS AGO AND YOU
CAN IMAGINE HOW EMOTIONAL HIS
RESPONSE WAS HERE TONIGHT.
>> AT THIS TIME OUR THANKS GO
OUT TO SO MANY PEOPLE, SO MANY
FRIENDS AND FAMILY AND COMPLETE
STRANGERS WHO WE DON'T KNOW, FOR
ALL THE LOVE, CONDOLENCES AND
SUPPORT YOU'VE GIVEN TO US.
MY DAUGHTER, EMILY, WOULD BE ONE
OF THE FIRST TO BE STANDING AND
GIVE UP HER LOVE AND SUPPORT TO
ALL THOSE VICTIMS BECAUSE THAT'S
THE TYPE OF PERSON THAT SHE IS.
NOT BECAUSE OF ANY PARENTING
THAT MY WIFE AND I COULD HAVE
DONE, BUT BECAUSE THOSE ARE THE
GIFTS THAT WERE GIVEN TO HER BY
HER HEAVENLY FATHER.
>> Bill: THERE IS MORE FROM
ROBBIE PARKER IN A MOMENT.
BUT FIRST, WE WANT TO TAKE YOU
LIVE TO NEW HAMPSHIRE.
THIS IS A SPOKESPERSON NOW FOR
THE LANZA FAMILY AND THE POLICE
DEPARTMENT UP THERE, THIS IS THE
FIRST TIME WE'VE HEARD ON BEHALF
OF PETER LANZA, THE FATHER OF
THE ALLEGED GUNMAN AND HIS SON,
RYAN, AGE 24, WHO LIVED IN
HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY.
LET'S DROP IN THERE NOW IN NEW
HAMPSHIRE.
>> THE LOSS WE ALL SHARE.
OUR HEARTS AND PRAYERS ARE WITH
THOSE WHO SHARE IN THIS LOSS.
THE FAMILIES, TEACHERS, STAFF
AND THE STUDENTS OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, THE FIRST
RESPONDERS AND TO ALL OTHERS
TOUCHED BY THIS TRAGEDY.
ON BEHALF OF NANCY'S MOTHER AND
SIBLINGS, WE REACH OUT TO THE
COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN AND EXPRESS
OUR HEARTFELT SORROW FOR THE
INCOMPREHENSIBLE AND PROFOUND
LOSS OF INNOCENTS THAT HAS
AFFECTED SO MANY.
THE FAMILY REQUESTS THAT YOU
RESPECT THEIR PRIVACY DURING
THIS TIME OF ANGUISH AND LOSS.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> ARE THERE ANY QUESTIONS, LIKE
I SAID, THERE IS NOT AN AWFUL
LOT WE CAN ANSWER.
>> TALK ABOUT THE F.B.I. AND
OTHER AUTHORITIES BEING --
>> THE ONLY THING I CAN TELL YOU
IS THAT LAW ENFORCEMENT
GENERALLY OBVIOUSLY VOLUNTEERED
ANY ASSISTANCE TO CONNECTICUT.
AND OUR RESPONDING TO ANY
REQUESTS THAT COME OUT OF
CONNECTICUT, THE REQUESTS THAT
THEY'RE MAKING OF US AND OUR
RESPONSE BACK TO THEM WILL GO
THROUGH THE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE AND WE WON'T HAVE ANY
COMMENT ABOUT THAT OTHER THAN
WE'LL DO ANYTHING WE CAN TO
HELP.
>> (INAUDIBLE).
>> CHIEF BRIGGS HERE.
>> VERY, VERY KIND, CONSIDERATE,
LIVED HERE GOOD PART OF HER
LIFE.
SHE WAS VERY INVOLVED IN THE
COMMUNITY.
VERY WELL RESPECTED.
>> DID YOU TALK ABOUT THE FAMILY
IN GENERAL?
>> I CAN TELL YOU SMALL TOWN,
THAT MRS. CHAMPION, DOTTY,
WORKED AS THE SCHOOL NURSE AT
THE DANIEL J. BAKEY SCHOOL FOR A
NUMBER OF YEARS.
A WONDERFUL PERSON, VERY GOOD
WITH CHILDREN.
JIM CHAMPION WORKED FOR ME FOR A
NUMBER OF YEARS AS THE CAPTAIN
OF THE POLICE DEPARTMENT AND HE
CURRENTLY WORKS FOR ME AS A
PART-TIME OFFICER, AS WELL AS
FOR A DEPUTY.
>> (INAUDIBLE).
>> THE WHOLE FAMILY IS
TRAUMATIZED BY THIS EVENT.
VERY SAD.
>> (INAUDIBLE).
>> I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T HEAR THAT.
I HAVE NOT.
HE HAS NOT.
>> (QUESTION INAUDIBLE).
>> I HAVE NOT HAD A CONVERSATION
WITH HIM.
VERY CLOSE.
>> (QUESTION INAUDIBLE).
>> I ACTUALLY SAW HER LAST
NOVEMBER WHEN JIM CHAMPION
RETIRED.
I SAW HER AT THE RETIREMENT
PARTY.
I HAVEN'T SEEN THE CHILDREN
SINCE THEY LEFT HERE IN 1998.
MY UNDERSTANDING WAS IT WAS
1998.
THAT WAS MY UNDERSTANDING.
>> ANY OTHER QUESTIONS?
THANKS A LOT.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Bill: LET'S PIECE THIS
TOGETHER HERE.
THOSE ARE SPOKES PEOPLE IN
KINGSTON, NEW HAMPSHIRE, WHICH
IS WHERE NANCY LANZA, HER MAIDEN
NAME IS CHAMPION.
SHE'S THE MOTHER OF THE ALLEGED
KILLER BACK HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
IT IS OUR UNDERSTANDING THAT SHE
WAS DIVORCED MAYBE FOUR YEARS
AGO, BUT HER HUSBAND, PETER,
STILL MADE HIS HOME HERE IN THE
STATE OF CONNECTICUT.
HOW FAR AWAY IS NOT CLEAR AT THE
MOMENT.
AND HIS OTHER SON, RYAN LANZA,
AGE 24, WHO WAS THE PERSON WHO
MANY THOUGHT WAS THE GUILTY
PARTY ON THIS EARLY ON, WAS
LIVING IN HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY.
WE WANTED TO BRING THAT YOU
BECAUSE WE'RE TRYING TO PIECE
THIS TOGETHER THROUGHOUT THE
ENTIRE DAY BECAUSE HERE IN
CONNECTICUT, POLICE SAY THERE IS
STILL NO SIGN, AT LEAST PUBLICLY
ANYWAY, THERE HAS BEEN NO SIGN
OF A MOTIVE.
BUT WE ARE LEARNING MORE ABOUT
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA AS WE
MOVE THROUGHOUT THE HOUR.
HERE IS A PICTURE SAID TO BE
FROM 2005 WHICH WOULD MEAN
AROUND THE AGE OF 14 SHOWN HERE.
SOURCES TELLING FOX NEWS HE MAY
HAVE HAD A DEVELOPMENTAL
DISORDER AND PEOPLE WHO KNEW THE
SHOOTER NOW DESCRIBE HIM AS
SMART BUT, QUOTE, VERY REMOTE
SOCIALLY.
ACCORDING TO STATE POLICE, THE
EVIDENCE NOW SUGGESTS THAT NO
ONE FROM THE SCHOOL ALLOWED HIM
TO GET INSIDE THE BUILDING
AROUND 9:30 IN THE MORNING
FRIDAY MORNING.
INSTEAD SOMEHOW HE FORCED HIS
WAY IN.
IT'S NOT CLEAR EXACTLY HOW.
TODAY A LIBRARY CLERK CONFIRMED
SHE AND OTHERS INSIDE THE SCHOOL
LEARNED THAT SOMETHING WAS WRONG
ONCE THEY HEARD THE GUN FIRE
COME ACROSS THE INTERCOM.
>> THE INTERCOM IN THE OFFICE
WENT OFF AS IF THEY WERE GOING
TO MAKE AN ANNOUNCEMENT AND THEN
WE HEARD SCUFFLING NOISES AND
STUFF AND I THOUGHT SOMEBODY HAD
HIT THE BUTTON BY MISTAKE AND
THEY WERE JUST IN THE OFFICE.
SOY CALLED DOWN THERE AND ONE OF
THE SECRETARIES ABDOMEN THE
PHONE AND SAID THERE IS A
SHOOTING.
AND THEN YOU BECOME AWARE, WE
STARTED HEARING THE GUN SHOTS.
I YELLED LOCKDOWN TO THE GROUP
THAT WAS IN OUR ROOM AND I RAN
ACROSS THE HALL AND TOLD THE
CLASSROOM ACROSS THE HALL TO
LOCK DOWN.
>> SHE HAD A LOT TO SAY EARLIER
TODAY.
SOME OF THE PICTURES YOU SEE
NOW, HUG A TEACHER TODAY, ARE
HANGING IN THE BUILDINGS
THROUGHOUT THE AREA OF NEWTOWN.
THE INVESTIGATION REALLY IN ITS
EARLY STAGES.
EARLIER TODAY, THE LEAD POLICE
OFFICER FROM THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT SAID THAT IT WILL BE
AT LEAST A DAY OR TWO AT A
MINIMUM BEFORE THE CRIME SCENE
IS EVALUATED ENTIRELY INSIDE AND
OUTSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
HERE IN NEWTOWN, THEY COME TO
GRIPS WITH THE LOSS OF 26 OF
THEIR OWN AND HOW IN THE WORLD
DO YOU BEGIN TO DO THAT?
THAT SIGN HANGS OUTSIDE OF A
RESTAURANT ENCOURAGING FOLKS TO
HUG A TEACHER AND THERE ARE MANY
OF US WHO FEEL THAT WAY TODAY
ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
MOLLY LINE IS WITH ME KNOW.
WHAT MORE DO WE KNOW ABOUT THE
VICTIMS?
GOOD EVENING TO YOU.
>> THEY RELEASED THIS HEART
BREAKING LIST.
WE KNEW IT WAS COMING.
WE KNEW THERE WOULD BE 20
CHILDREN'S NAMES AND SIX ADULTS.
NOW WE KNOW THAT ALL SIX OF
THOSE ADULTS WERE WOMEN THAT
WERE AT THE SCHOOL THAT DAY
TRYING TO PROTECT THEIR
STUDENTS.
THAT THERE WERE 20 CHILDREN
THERE AND AS YOU MENTIONED, SOME
OF THESE NAMES, THESE ARE NAMES
YOU HEAR IN ANY CLASSROOM,
CHARLOTTE, CHASE, JESSE, EMILY,
AS YOU MENTIONED.
WE WATCHED HER FATHER SPEAK
EARLIER TONIGHT.
LITTLE KIDS THAT WERE SIX AND
SEVEN YEARS OLD.
LITTLE, LITTLE CHILDREN.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT LITTLE GIRLS
AND LITTLE BOYS.
THEY WERE LITERALLY GUNNED DOWN
IN THEIR FIRST GRADE CLASSROOM
WEARING WHAT THEIR PARENTS
DRESSED THEM IN THAT DAY.
THE NORMAL CHEERFUL CLOTHES IS
THE WAY THE MEDICAL EXAMINER
DESCRIBED IT.
>> Bill: HIS PRESS CONFERENCE I
THOUGHT WAS ESPECIALLY CHILLING.
WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT THE LINE OF
WORK THIS MAN IS IN, GENTLEMAN
NAMED WAYNE CARVER, I THINK IT
WAS LIKELY JOLTING AND JARRING
TO A LOT OF PEOPLE LISTENING TO
HIM TELL US ABOUT WHAT HE IS
LEARNING ABOUT HOW SOME OF THESE
CHILDREN DIED.
>> HE DID SPEAK SOMETIMES IN
CLINICAL TERMS, WHICH THAT CAN
BE A LITTLE JARRING FOR PEOPLE
THAT ARE WAITING TO HEAR WHAT
HAPPENED.
HE ESSENTIALLY SAID THERE WERE
MULTIPLE GUN SHOTS WOUNDS TO
EVERYONE THAT WAS KILLED, THAT
HIS PERSONAL EXAMINATION OF
SEVEN OF THE VICTIMS, EACH OF
THEM HAD BETWEEN THREE AND 11
GUN SHOTS THAT, INCLUDED THE
CHILDREN, THAT INCLUDED THE
ADULTS.
NO ONE ESCAPED THE WRATH OF THIS
GUN WHICH HE BELIEVES THE IMPACT
CAME FROM THE RIFLE THAT THEY
BELIEVE WAS USED.
WE DO KNOW THAT THERE WERE OTHER
GUNS INVOLVED IN THE SCENE,
THERE WERE OTHER GUNS FOUND, BUT
THEY'RE TRYING TO CLARIFY IF
THEY WERE USED.
WHEN WE TALK ABOUT THE GUNSHOT
WOUNDS ON THE VICTIM, THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER BELIEVES IT WAS
THE RIFLE.
>> Bill: THANK YOU.
WE'LL TALK TO YOU LATER
THROUGHOUT OUR PROGRAM AS WE
CONTINUE FOR THE NEXT TWO HOURS.
WHEN YOU HEAR THAT MEDICAL
EXAMINER SAY THAT A SIX OR
SEVEN-YEAR-OLD CHILD WAS SHOT 11
TIMES, IT'S QUITE EXTRAORDINARY
TO TAKE THAT INFORMATION IN AS
HE WAS DELIVERING HERE TONIGHT.
MOLLY, THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Bill: WE HAVE A LOT MORE HERE
LIVE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
BECAUSE WE'RE WORKING THROUGH
THE HOUR TO LEARN MORE ABOUT THE
SHOOTER AND WHY HE MAY HAVE
CHOSEN TO COMMIT THIS CRIME.
WE'RE GOING TO TALK TO THE
FRIEND OF THE GUNMAN'S BROTHER
WHO HAS SOME INTERESTING THINGS
TO SAY ABOUT THE RELATIONSHIP
BETWEEN THE BROTHERS AND WE'LL
GET TO THAT AS OUR COVERAGE
CONTINUES LIVE IN NEWTOWN IN A
MOMENT HERE ON THIS SPECIAL
EDITION OF THE FOX REPORT.
>> Bill: THE SCHOOL TRAGEDY
COVERAGE CONTINUES LIVE HERE ON
THE FOX NEWS CHANNEL.
WE ARE LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT AND LEARNING MORE
ABOUT THE GUNMAN, ADAM LANZA,
AGE 20.
HE MAY HAVE SUFFERED FROM A
PERSONALITY DISORDER.
AS MENTIONED, SOME WHO KNEW HIM
DESCRIBED HIM AS SMART BUT
CONSIDERED REMOTE.
ONE PERSON EVEN SAID VERY
REMOTE.
BRETT IS A FRIEND OF ADAM'S
BROTHER.
HE IS RYAN LANZA, AGE 24.
BRETT IS WITH ME BY TELEPHONE.
GOOD EVENING TO YOU.
TELL ME ABOUT YOUR RELATIONSHIP
WITH THE OLDER BROTHER.
>> I'VE KNOWN RYAN FOR ABOUT A
YEAR AND A HALF.
MET HIM THROUGH MUTUAL FRIENDS.
MY RELATIONSHIP WITH HIM IS I'LL
SEE HIM ABOUT ONCE A MONTH AND
WE'LL HANG OUT FOR A LITTLE
WHILE AND THEN KIND OF BACK TO
AN ON-LINE RELATIONSHIP OF
SORTS.
>> Bill: DO YOU LIVE IN HOBOKEN,
NEW JERSEY, AROUND THAT AREA,
BRETT?
>> NO, BUT I WORK THERE.
I'M THERE FREQUENTLY ENOUGH TO
SEE HIM, AND OTHER MUTUAL
FRIENDS.
>> Bill: WHAT DO YOU KNOW ABOUT
HIS RELATIONSHIP WITH HIS
YOUNGER BROTHER, ADAM?
>> UNFORTUNATELY, I DIDN'T EVEN
KNOW HE HAD A YOUNGER BROTHER
UNTIL FRIDAY MORNING.
LED TO A LOT OF CONFUSION AND
MISINFORMATION.
MOSTLY BECAUSE I DON'T KNOW HIM
WELL ENOUGH TO KNOW A LOT OF
PERSONAL DETAILS ABOUT HIS
FAMILY.
OTHER THAN THAT, YEAH.
THAT WAS THE FIRST I HEARD ABOUT
IT.
>> Bill: YOU'VE KNOWN HIM FOR A
YEAR AND A HALF AND A
CONVERSATION ABOUT HIS BROTHER
NEVER CAME UP?
>> CORRECT.
YEAH.
I DON'T THINK HE KNOWS AS MUCH
ABOUT MY FAMILY EITHER.
>> Bill: THERE IS A REPORT
EARLIER TODAY THAT THESE TWO
BROTHERS HAVE NOT HAD CONTACT
FOR AT LEAST TWO YEARS.
NOW, THAT'S UNCONFIRMED.
WE DON'T KNOW THAT.
BUT BASED ON YOUR RELATIONSHIP
AND THE WAY YOU'RE DESCRIBING
IT, I WOULD IMAGINE YOU DON'T
HAVE ANY INFORMATION ON THAT, DO
YOU?
>> I DON'T.
I'VE HEARD THAT, TOO.
WHAT I CAN TELL YOU IS THAT RYAN
HIMSELF IS A VERY QUIET AND
SOMEWHAT PRIVATE GUY.
IT'S NOT UNLIKE WHAT WE'RE
HEARING ABOUT ADAM.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU CAN DRAW
FROM THAT OTHER THAN THE FACT
THAT HE JUST DOESN'T OPEN UP TOO
EASILY, BUT IT WAS NEVER REALLY
IN ANYONE'S POSITION TO TRY TO
PRY IT OUT OF HIM.
>> Bill: HAVE YOU TALKED TO HIM
TODAY?
DID YOU TALK TO HIM YESTERDAY?
WHEN WAS YOUR LAST CONVERSATION?
>> YESTERDAY AT ABOUT
2:00 O'CLOCK, THEREABOUTS.
I JUST SENT HIM A MESSAGE ON
FACEBOOK AS I REALIZED THAT THE
MAGNITUDE OF WHAT WAS HAPPENING
AND THE REALITY OF WHAT WAS
GOING ON, JUST TO SEE IF HE WAS
OKAY AND WHAT WAS HAPPENING AND
HE RESPONDED BACK WITH --
>> Bill: WHAT DID HE TELL YOU?
>> HE JUST SAID -- ALL HE SAID
WAS, IT WAS MY BROTHER, OH, MY
GOD.
I THINK MY MOM IS DEAD.
AND THEN THAT WAS THE LAST I
HEARD FROM HIM.
I HAVEN'T HEARD FROM HIM TODAY
EITHER.
>> Bill: BRETT, THANK YOU.
WE'RE WORKING THROUGH THIS ALSO.
APPRECIATE YOUR INPUT.
BRETT, A FRIEND OF RYAN LANZA,
AGE 24.
AS WE CONTINUE TO FOLLOW THE
LATEST DEVELOPMENTS OUT OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
IN A MOMENT, MORE COMMENTS FROM
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER THAT WERE
SO CHILLING AND WE'RE LEARNING
OF ANOTHER ALLEGED SCHOOL
SHOOTING PLOT FOILED BY POLICE
THE SAME DAY THE CONNECTICUT
TRAGEDY UNFOLDED.
DETAILS ON THAT IN A MOMENT.
ALSO THERE IS OTHER NEWS AND
SIGNIFICANT NEWS.
THE SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON RESTING AT HER HOME
AFTER A CONCUSSION.
APPARENTLY SHE FELL RECENTLY.
THE LATEST ON HER HEALTH SCARE
AND THE BREAKING DETAILS AND
WHETHER OR NOT SHE'LL BE ABLE TO
TESTIFY AT THE HEARINGS ON
BENGHAZI SCHEDULED FOR LATER
THIS WEEK AND WHO MIGHT REPLACE
HER AT THE DEPARTMENT OF STATE
YOU WON'T TAKE MY LIFE.
YOU WON'T TAKE OUR FUTURE.
AIDS AFFECTS US ALL.
EVEN BABIES.
CHEVRON IS WORKING TO STOP
MOTHER-TO-CHILD TRANSMISSION.
OUR EMPLOYEES AND THEIR FAMILIES
ARE PART OF THE FIGHT.
AND WE'RE WINNING.
AT CHEVRON NIGERIA, WE HAVEN'T
HAD A REPORTED CASE IN 12EARS.
AIDS IS STRONG.
BUT WE ARE STRONGER.
AND AIDS...
♪
AIDS IS GOING TO LOSE.
>> Bill: OUR CONTINUING COVERAGE
OF THE SCHOOL TRAGEDY HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, CONTINUES.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER TWO HOURS
AGO WAS ASKED WHERE THE YOUNG
BOYS AND GIRLS WERE SHOT.
HIS ANSWER WAS ONE WORD.
EVERYWHERE.
WHEN YOU LISTEN TO WHAT HE SAYS
ABOUT THE EXAMINATION OF THE SIX
AND SEVEN-YEAR-OLD BOYS AND
GIRLS AND THEIR BODIES AND THE
CONDITION IN WHICH THEY WERE
FOUND, IT IS STUNNING AND WE'RE
GOING TO HAVE A BIT MORE OF THAT
A BIT LATER IN OUR PROGRAM.
BUT THERE IS SOME OTHER NEWS
MAKING HEADLINES NOW.
SOURCES TELLING FOX NEWS THAT
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS EXPECTED TO
NOMINATE DEMOCRATIC
MASSACHUSETTS SENATOR JOHN KERRY
TO BE THE NEXT SECRETARY OF
STATE.
HE WOULD REPLACE HILLARY CLINTON
AS THE NATION'S TOP DIPLOMAT.
SHE'S EXPECTED TO STEP DOWN
EARLY NEXT YEAR.
ALL THIS COMING NOW ONLY DAYS
AFTER AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE TOOK
HERSELF OUT OF CONTENTION FOR
THE JOB.
ALTHOUGH SHE WAS NOT OFFICIALLY
NOMINATED.
OUR CHIEF WHITE HOUSE
CORRESPONDENT ED HENRY TRACKING
ALL THIS.
ED, WHAT DO YOU HAVE ON THIS?
GOOD EVENING.
>> GOOD EVENING.
I SPOKE TO A SOURCE CLOSE TO THE
PROC
BASICALLY A DONE DEAL NOW.
THE PRESIDENT IS EXPECTED TO
PICK SENATOR JOHN KERRY.
IT'S LIKE LOW TO HAPPEN IN A
MATTER OF DAYS.
THERE IS REALLY ONLY TWO THINGS
HOLING THIS UP RIGHT NOW.
THAT IS NUMBER ONE, THE
PRESIDENT WANTS TO DO IT ALL
TOGETHER, YOU KNOW, ENTIRELY NEW
NATIONAL SECURITY TEAM.
THAT WOULD INCLUDE A NEW
PENTAGON CHIEF, A NEW C.I.A.
DIRECTOR.
HE'D LIKE TO PICK THE ACTING
DIRECTOR OR SECURITY ADVISOR.
AT THE PENTAGON, MORE
COMPLICATED.
THE LIKELY PICK STILL IS CHUCK
HAGEL.
BIPARTISANSHIP IN THE CABINET.
THERE HAS BEEN CRITICISM IN
RECENT DAYS FROM SOME FOLKS
SUGGESTING THAT IN THE SENATE,
CHUCK HAGEL, HIS STANCE TOWARD
ISRAEL WAS PERHAPS NOT STRONG
ENOUGH FOR SOME.
THE WHITE HOUSE IS WORKING
THROUGH THOSE CONCERNS --
>> Bill: MEANWHILE, SECRETARY
CLINTON IS RECOVERING AT HOME
TONIGHT.
THIS AFTER FAINTING AND
SUFFERING A CONCUSSION.
THIS WAS BREAKING NEWS EARLIER
TODAY.
THIS IS SOMETHING WE DID NOT
KNOW.
STATE DEPARTMENT SPOKESMAN SAYS
THAT IT HAPPENED AS A RESULT OF
A STOMACH VIRUS,  WHICH HAS LEFT
SECRETARY CLINTON WEAK AND
DEHYDRATED.
THE SECRETARY ALREADY SKIPPING
AN OVERSEAS TRIP TO NORTH AFRICA
AND THE PERSIAN GULF BECAUSE OF
THE ILLNESS.
NOW WE'RE BEING TOLD SHE WILL
MISS A CONGRESSIONAL HEARING ON
THE ATTACK ON THE CONSULATE IN
LIBYA.
DOCTORS NOW KEEPING AN EYE ON
HER UNTIL SHE FULLY RECOVERS.
ED HENRY WORKING HIS STORY AGAIN
TONIGHT MORE DEVELOPMENTS FROM
ED AS WE GET THEM HERE.
NOW TO A SHOCKING STORY OUT OF
OKLAHOMA.
ON THE SAME DAY CONNECTICUT WAS
TORN APART BY THIS TRAGEDY,
ANOTHER SCHOOL SHOOTING PLOT
THERE WAS FOILED.
POLICE ARRESTING EIGHT-YEAR-OLD
SAMMY CHAVEZ EARLY ON FRIDAY
MORNING.
THEY SAY HE WAS PLANNING TO KILL
CLASSMATES AT BARTERERSVILLE
HIGH SCHOOL A SMALL FOUND
50 MILES NORTH OF TULSA,
OKLAHOMA.
OFFICIALS SAYING CHAVEZ TRIED TO
CONVINCE OTHER STUDENTS TO HELP
HIM LURE KIDS INTO THE SCHOOL'S
AUDITORIUM, CHAIN THE DOOR SHUT
AND START SHOOTING.
LOCAL REPORTS SAY HE EVEN
THREATENED TO KILL CLASSMATES
WHO DID NOT HELP AND THAT HE WAS
GOING TO SET OFF BOMBS AS POLICE
ARRIVED.
HE'S BEING HELD ON A MILLION
DOLLARS BOND THERE IN OKLAHOMA.
>>> WE WATCHED THE LATEST HERE
FROM NEWTOWN AND WE HAVE LEARNED
A LOT MORE THROUGHOUT THE DAY
TODAY.
ON THE PSYCHOLOGICAL EFFECTS
THAT SOMETHING LIKE THIS CAN
HAVE ON CHILDREN AND WHAT IT CAN
HAVE ON ADULTS, THE PARENTS
TRYING THEIR BEST TO DEAL WITH
THIS AND TO LIVE WITH THIS.
WHAT THE EXPERTS SAY IS THE BEST
WAY TO TALK TO YOUR KIDS ABOUT
THE TRAGEDY COMING UP FROM OUR
OWN EXPERTS AT THE FOX NEWS
CHANNEL.
ALSO GOVERNOR MIKE HUCKABEE IS
WITH US LATER FOR HIS TAKE ON
HOW WE UNDERSTAND THE SHOOTINGS
IN NEWTOWN
There is no
mass-produced human.
So we created the
extraordinarily
comfortable Sleep Number
Experience.
around a bed with DualAir
Technology that allows you
to adjust to the support
your body needs - each of
your bodies.
Our sleep professionals will
help you find
your sleep number setting.
Exclusively at a Sleep
Number store.
Sleep Number.
Comfort individualized.
This holiday season, give
the gift that's magical:
the innovative AirFit
adjustable pillow at
special 30% savings.
>> Bill: I'M BILL HEMMER.
WELCOME BACK TO OUR SPECIAL
EDITION OF THE FOX REPORT.
FOR TWO HOURS TONIGHT LIVE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
AS WE WORK FOR MORE INFORMATION
ABOUT THE VICTIMS OF YESTERDAY'S
DEADLY SCHOOL SHOOTING, THAT NOW
WE KNOW INCLUDED 12 GIRLS AND
EIGHT BOYS, ALL OF THEM EITHER
AGE SIX OR AGE SEVEN.
THAT'S THE WORD FROM THE
CONNECTICUT CHIEF MEDICAL
EXAMINER WHO SAYS THIS IS THE
WORST MASSACRE HE HAS EVER SEEN
AND THAT INCLUDES 31 YEARS OF
WORK HERE IN THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT.
WE HEARD FROM ROBBIE PARKER
ABOUT AN HOUR AGO.
HE'S A FATHER OF ONE OF THE
VICTIMS, HIS DAUGHTER WAS EMILY.
HE SAYS HE'S NOT MAD, BUT HE
TALKED ABOUT HIS DAUGHTER A LOT.
HE SAID SHE WOULD LIGHT UP A
ROOM, ALWAYS HAD SOMETHING NICE
TO SAY ABOUT EVERYONE.
THEN HE SAID, I'M SO BLESSED TO
BE HER DAD.
THAT FROM ROBBIE PARKER WHO IS
STRUGGLING FOR ANSWERS HERE
TONIGHT IN NEWTOWN.
THIS WAS A TOWN, BY THE WAY,
THAT JUST RECENTLY WAS LISTED IN
THE TOP FIVE SAFEST COMMUNITIES
TO LIVE IN THE ENTIRE COUNTRY.
FROM THIS DAY FORWARD, THE TOWN
OF NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WILL
ALWAYS BE REMEMBERED FOR THE
MASSACRE THAT OCCURRED HERE ONLY
36 HOURS AGO.
WE WERE IN TOWN A SHORT TIME AGO
AND FOUND THIS.
>> THIS IS THE TOWN HALL IN
NEWTOWN, THE CENTER PART OF THIS
TOWN AND AS WE HAVE SEEN
THROUGHOUT THE AREA, THESE
MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS THAT ARE SET
UP.
CHEERLY THESE ARE CANDLES LIT
YESTERDAY AFTERNOON AND LAST
NIGHT AND MANY MORE GATHERED A
BIT EARLIER TODAY.
NEWTOWN COVERS A LARGE AREA, BUT
FRANKLY NOT A LOT OF PEOPLE LIVE
HERE.
POPULATION ABOUT 27,000.
IT'S QUITE STRIKING WHEN YOU SEE
THE VICTORRIAN HOMES UP AND DOWN
THE MAIN STREET IN NEWTOWN.
IT IS A BEAUTIFUL SMALL TOWN.
LATE IN THE AFTERNOON, IT HAS
BEEN PEACEFUL FOR SO LONG.
THE LAST SERIOUS CRIME REPORTED
HERE TWO YEARS AGO IN 2010.
TODAY A MUCH DIFFERENT PICTURE.
PART OF THAT PICTURE, AS WE MOVE
FURTHER DOWN THE ROAD IS ANOTHER
MAKESHIFT MEMORIAL WHERE WE HAVE
SEEN PEOPLE DROP OFF FLOWERS
THROUGHOUT THE AFTERNOON HERE.
THIS IS THE FLAG POLE IN
NEWTOWN.
IT IS A TOWN LANDMARK, TEN
STORIES TALL, MORE THAN 100 FEET
HERE IN THE CENTRAL PART OF THE
TOWN.
THIS FLAG IS AT HALF-STAFF, THE
PRESIDENT ORDERED THEM
THROUGHOUT THE COUNTRY AND ALL
MILITARY INSTITUTIONS YESTERDAY
AFTERNOON.
IF YOU WERE TO DRIVE TWO MILES
DOWN THIS BEAUTIFUL COUNTRY
ROAD, THAT IS WHERE YOU WOULD
FIND THE SCENE OF CARNAGE THAT
AMERICA FOUND YESTERDAY.
I MENTIONED ROBBIE PARKER, THE
FATHER OF YOUNG EMILY A MOMENT
AGO.
I WANT TO BRING IN THE GOVERNOR,
MIKE HUCKABEE.
YOU'VE HAD SO MANY ELOQUENT
THINGS TO SAY THROUGHOUT THE DAY
TODAY.
I GUESS WHAT STRUCK ME SO MUCH
LISTENING TO ROBBIE PARKER, HE
SAYS, I DON'T KNOW HOW TO GET
THROUGH THIS.
AND THEN HE SAID, THE BEST THING
I CAN DO IS HELP OTHER PEOPLE.
HOW ARE YOU PIECING THIS
TOGETHER TONIGHT, GOVERNOR?
>> IT WAS SO ELOQUENT TO HEAR
HIM.
I TELL YOU WHAT STRUCK ME TODAY,
WHEN WE STARTED LOOKING AT THE
LIST OF THESE KIDS, THEIR NAMES,
THEIR AGES, IT STARTED MAKING IT
MORE REAL, I THINK, THEN IT'S
BEEN SINCE IT FIRST WAS
ANNOUNCED.
SUDDENLY YOU REALIZE THESE
CHILDREN HAD NAMES AND ADDRESSES
AND BROTHERS AND SISTERS AND
MOTHERS, FATHERS, AUNTS, UNCLES,
GRANDPARENTS AND YOU REALIZE THE
HORRIFIC TRAGEDY, DEEPLY
PERSONNEL.
THEN TO SEE THIS FATHER OF EMILY
PARKER EXPRESS THAT GRIEF AND
REALLY JUST REACH OUT.
I THINK IT MAKES ALL OF THIS I
GUESS A STARK REMINDER OF HOW
HORRIBLE THE TRAGEDY IS, BUT
ALSO HOW PEOPLE LEARN TO COPE.
THAT'S WHAT AMERICA IS TRYING TO
DO.
I THINK EVERYBODY IS JUST
LEARNING TO TRY TO COPE WITH
GRIEF.
>> Bill: SO MANY HAVE TOLD ME
JUST IN THE PAST DAY THAT THEY
WILL TURN ON THEIR TELEVISION
AND JUST LEAVE IT ON AND WATCH
AND CRY AND DO THAT FOR HOURS.
THAT'S PART OF THIS PROCESS OF
GRIEF, IS IT NOT?
>> IT'S AN IMPORTANT PROCESS.
SOMETIMES PEOPLE SAY WHAT, CAN
WE DO?
WHAT CAN WE SAY?
I THINK THE LESS WE SAY THE
BETTER.
BECAUSE IF YOU'RE TRYING TO TALK
TO SOMEONE WHO IS IN GRIEF, THEY
DON'T WANT TO HEAR OUR WORDS.
THEY WANT O FEEL OUR TOUCH.
THEY WANT TO KNOW THAT WE'RE
THERE WITH THEM, THAT WE HAVEN'T
ABANDONED THEM AND THERE ISN'T
ANYTHING ANYBODY CAN SAY THAT
MAKES THIS BETTER.
I WAS REMINDED EARLIER TODAY
WHEN I WAS TALKING WITH JOHN
SCOTT, THE SHORTEST VERSE IN THE
BIBLE MAY BE THE MOST POWERFUL,
JESUS WEPT.
HE LEFT HAND HIS FRIEND DIED AND
HE CRIED ABOUT IT.
THAT SORT OF SAYS IT ALL, THAT
SOMETIMES THE MOST POWERFUL
THING THAT WE CAN DO TO GET
THROUGH OUR OWN GRIEF IS TO
RECOGNIZE THAT WE HAVE IT AND BE
HONEST ABOUT IT AND EXPRESS IT.
DON'T HOLD THE TEARS BACK, BUT
LET THEM FLOW.
IT'S HOW WE WERE HARD WIRED IN
ORDER TO BE ABLE TO EXPRESS AND
TO ACKNOWLEDGE THAT THERE IS A
DEEP HUMAN PAIN THAT IS GOING ON
INSIDE OF US.
>> Bill: YOU KNOW, YOUR PREVIOUS
LIFE, YOU WERE A GOVERNOR OF
ARKANSAS.
>> YES.
>> Bill: YOU HAD TO DEAL WITH
NATURAL DISASTERS AND HUMAN
DISASTERS AND THE TRAGEDY THAT
MAN INFLICTS UPON OTHER MEN AND
YOU HAD TO FACE THOSE VICTIMS OR
YOU HAD TO FACE THOSE WHO WERE
TRYING TO MOVE ON WITH THEIR OWN
LIVES.
WHAT DID YOU DO AS THE HEAD OF
THAT STATE?
>> I REMEMBER THE DAY AFTER THE
JONESBORO SHOOTING IN MARCH OF
1998, WHICH AN 11 AND
12-YEAR-OLD OPENED FIRED ON
THEIR CLASSMATES AND TEACHERS.
IT WAS THE MOST HORRIFIC THING I
WENT THROUGH AS A GOVERNORMENT I
SPENT THE NEXT DAY VISITING THE
SURVIVORS IN THE HOSPITAL AND
THEN I MET WITH THE ENTIRE STAFF
OF THE SCHOOL.
BEHIND CLOSED DOORS, NO PRESS.
IT WAS A VOCA -- VOCA THAT IS
RIGHTIC EXPERIENCE, IT WAS A LOT
OF CRYING, A LOT OF PEOPLE
SHARING THEIR FEELINGS TOWARD
THOSE WHO HAD BEEN KILLED AND
TRYING TO UNDERSTAND WHAT HAD
HAPPENED.
AGAIN, IT WAS VERY SIMILAR TO
WHAT HAPPENED IN CONNECTICUT.
NOBODY CAN IMAGINE THAT KIDS
THAT AGE COULD DO SOMETHING AND
LEAVE THAT MUCH CARNAGE AND THAT
MUCH PAIN BEHIND.
THERE ARE ALWAYS PEOPLE WHO WILL
BE QUICK TO SAY OKAY.
WHAT COULD WE HAVE DONE TO
PREVENT IT?
THERE WILL BE PLENTY OF TIME FOR
PEOPLE TO MAKE ALL THE SECOND
GUESSING THEY WANT TO MAKE.
BUT I THINK RIGHT NOW WHAT
PEOPLE NEED TO DO IS BRING AS
MUCH COMFORT AS POSSIBLE.
WE DON'T UNDERSTAND ALL OF THE
WHY OR -- WE WON'T UNDERSTAND
ALL OF THE WAYS TO FIX THIS.
THERE WILL BE PLENTY OF TIME FOR
TO US WORK ON THAT.
WE NEED TO COLLECTIVELY AS A
COUNTRY GRIEVE AND TO EXPRESS
OUR PRAYERS AND CONCERNS FOR
THESE WHO HAVE THE MOST AMAZING
GRIEF OF ALL AND THAT'S THE
PARENTS OF THESE CHILDREN.
>> Bill: GOVERNOR, THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Bill: I DON'T KNOW AND I WAS
NOT AWARE OF MANY SCHOOLS FROM
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADE THAT WENT INTO LOCKDOWN AT
9:30 IN THE MORNING.
BUT THIS IS A SCHOOL THAT HAD
THAT SAFETY FEATURE ALREADY
IMPLEMENTED IN THE SCHOOL.
AND AS IT TURNS OUT, IT NEEDED
IT AND IN THE END, IT PROBABLY
NEEDED MORE THAN THAT.
YOU CAN UNDERSTAND THAT IN NEW
YORK CITY, BUT UP HERE IN THE
COUNTRY SIDE AND TOWN OF 27,000,
CHECK OUT OF THE THE GOVERNOR
TONIGHT AT 8:00  O'CLOCK EASTERN
TIME.
HUCKABEE COMES YOUR WAY THERE.
HE'LL HAVE MUCH MORE ON THE
TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN IN HIS OWN
INTIMATE WAY HERE ON THE FOX
NEWS CHANNEL.
OUR THANKS TO THE GOVERNOR BEING
WITH US THIS EVENING.
DETAILS SLOWLY STARTING TO MORE
THAN ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
YESTERDAY INSIDE THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
SANDY HOOK.
AS THAT INVESTIGATION CONTINUES,
POLICE ARE URGING PATIENCE.
THERE HAS BEEN A STATE TROOPER
ASSIGNED TO EVERY FAMILY OF THE
VICTIMS AND THEY HAVE WARNED THE
MEDIA REPEATEDLY THROUGHOUT THE
DAY TODAY, GIVE THEM THEIR
SPACE.
GIVE THEM THE COMPASSION THAT
THEY NEED NOW.
WE WILL RESPECT THAT AS OUR
COVERAGE CONTINUES THROUGHOUT
THE EVENING HERE.
>> THIS STILL IS AN ACTIVE CASE.
WE ARE STILL WORKING AND
ACTIVELY PURSUING LEADS.
>> WE CAN SHOW AND SHARE WITH
EACH OTHER THE GRIEF WE FEEL FOR
THE CHILDREN AND ADULTS WHO WERE
KILLED.
AND FOR THEIR FAMILIES AND THEIR
LOVED ONES.
>> Bill: AS VECTORS TRY TO PIECE
TOGETHER WHAT HAPPENED, WHAT
GOES INTO INVESTIGATING SUCH A
TERRIBLE CRIME SCENE.
WHERE DO YOU START?
AT THE NEW YORK POLICE
DEPARTMENT, PRESIDENT, GOOD
EVENING TO YOU.
WE'VE HEARD A LOT FROM THE
POLICE DEPARTMENT UP HERE.
I THINK THEY HAVE BEEN STANDOUT
GENTLEMEN FOR THE PAST DAY AND A
HALF.
AT TIMES YOU WANT THEM TO GIVE
MORE INFORMATION, BUT YOU CAN
UNDERSTAND WHAT'S HAPPENING ON
THE OTHER SIDE OF THIS.
THEY ARE TRYING TO DO THIS THE
RIGHT WAY.
WHAT'S YOUR OBSERVATION ABOUT
WHAT THEY HAVE DONE SO FAR?
>> SO FAR THEY'VE DONE A GREAT
JOB AND REALLY GETTING EVERYBODY
TOGETHER AND USING ALL THE
POLICE DEPARTMENTS, ALL
RESOURCES, TALKING TO THE MEDIA.
THEY TELL THE FAMILIES WHAT'S
GOING ON A LOT MORE THAN THEY
WOULD THE MEDIA.
SO YOU CAN UNDERSTAND THAT.
BUT SPEAKING FOR ALL LAW
ENFORCEMENT, I WOULD HAVE TO SAY
WE ALL HAVE HAVE A HEAVY HEART
'CAUSE HOW WE THINK IS A LOT
DIFFERENT.
SOMETIMES WE THINK OF THE CRIME
SCENE.
SO WHAT WE CAN ACTUALLY
VISUALIZE THIS GUY GOING INTO
THE CLASSROOM WITH THAT RIFLE
AND HOW HE COULD SHOOT THOSE
MANY PEOPLE AND THAT'S WHAT THE
CRIME SCENE IS PUTTING TOGETHER,
HOW THAT HAPPENS.
THEY ALMOST VISUALIZE IT.
SO YOU KNOW THEY HAVE A HEAVY
HEART JUST PUTTING THIS THING
TOGETHER AND LOOKING AT KIDS
THAT ARE SHOT SO MUCH.
YOU KNOW, HAVING THIS GUY SHOOT
THEM LIKE THAT, IT REALLY WASN'T
A HARD THING FOR HIM TO DO.
>> Bill: SADLY, YOU'RE RIGHT
ABOUT THAT LAST COMMENT.
BUT IN THIS CASE, YOU HAVE TWO
CRIME SCENES.
NOT JUST AT THE SCHOOL, BUT AT
THE HOME OF THE MOTHER AND
APPARENTLY WHERE THIS
21-YEAR-OLD KILLER WAS LIVING.
WHAT THE POLICE SAID EARLIER IS
THAT THE MOTHER'S HOME, AND I'M
QUOTING NOW -- HAS PRODUCED SOME
GOOD EVIDENCE FOR INVESTIGATORS.
THERE IS NOT MUCH MORE DETAIL IN
THAT.
WE'RE TRYING TO READ THROUGH THE
LINES AND FIGURE OUT WHAT THAT
IS.
PUBLICLY WE DO NOT KNOW.
BUT THE HOME MAY LEAD TO MOTIVE,
RIGHT, GILL?
>> DEFINITELY.
WHERE THAT STATEMENT CAME OUT,
SURE, THEY THINK OF WHAT
HAPPENED MAYBE THROUGH HIS
EMOTIONAL STATE.
MAYBE SOME OF THE THINGS HE DID.
MAYBE PICTURES THAT HE HAS IN
THERE.
I'M NOT TOO SURE THEY FOUND
ANYTHING ON THE COMPUTER OR
ANYTHING ELSE.
BUT THEY LOOK AT HIS WHOLE
HISTORY, WHO DID HE TALK TO AND
ALL THAT.
THAT PICTURE IS GOING TO COME
OUT OF WHAT HAPPENED BECAUSE
REALLY WE ALL WANT TO KNOW WHY
AND THE FAMILIES MORE THAN
ANYBODY ELSE Y. THAT'S A
FRUSTRATING THING.
THE POLICE, YOU KNOW HOW ALL THE
INFORMATION CAME OUT AND A LOT
WAS WRONG.
SO THEY DON'T WANT TO COME OUT
WITH THAT INFORMATION.
SO THEY'RE TAKING THEIR TIME
WITH THIS.
IT'S GOING TO TAKE TIME.
THEY'RE TALKING TO THE FAMILIES.
SO THEY HAVE EVERYTHING REALLY
UNDER CONTROL UNDER THESE
SITUATIONS.
>> Bill: GILL, THANK YOU.
THANK YOU, SIR.
WE WERE TOLD EARLIER TODAY THAT
AT LEAST MONDAY AT THE EARLIEST
NOW BEFORE THEY CAN CLEAR THE
SCENE FROM A CRIMINAL
INVESTIGATION STANDPOINT AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THAT'S AT LEAST 48 HOURS AWAY.
AND THEY WERE CAREFUL NOT TO PUT
AN EXACT TIME FRAME ON IT, WHICH
GIVES YOU AN IDEA OF HOW MUCH
INFORMATION THEY HAVE TO GO
THROUGH INSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
WE ARE WATCHING THE STORY
THROUGHOUT THE EVENING TONIGHT.
THERE IS SOME OTHER NEWS,
THOUGH.
INCLUDING THE HISTORIC VOTE
UNDERWAY IN EGYPT THAT COULD
SHAPE THE FUTURE NOT ONLY FOR
THAT CRITICAL NATION AND MIDDLE
EASTERN POLITICS, BUT FOR ALL
POLITICS THROUGHOUT THE MIDDLE
EAST.
SO WE ARE LIVE IN CAIRO TRACKING
THAT.
ALSO A LOOK AT HOW THE DEADLY
SHOOTING HERE IN NEWTOWN COULD
CHANGE HOW SCHOOLS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY HANDLE THEIR OWN
SECURITY AS OUR COVERAGE
CONTINUES.
>> FORTIFY OUR ELEMENTARY
SCHOOLS AND MAKE THEM LIKE A
FORT TEXAS RANGERS -- FORTRESS,
OUR SOCIETY SHOULD NOT BE THAT
WAY
EAT GOOD FATS.
AVOID BAD.
DON'T GO OVER 2000...
1200 CALORIES A DAY.
CARBS ARE BAD. CARBS ARE GOOD.
THE STORY KEEPS CHANGING.
SO I'M NOT LISTENING...
TO ANYONE BUT MYSELF.
I KNOW BETTER NUTRITION
WHEN I SEE IT:
GREAT GRAINS.
GREAT GRAINS CEREAL STARTS
WHOLE AND STAYS WHOLE.
SEE THE SEAM?
MORE PROCESSED FLAKES LOOK
NOTHING LIKE NATURALRAINS.
YOU CAN'T ARGUE WITH
NUTRITION YOU CAN SEE.
GREAT GRAINS.
SEARCH GREAT GRAINS
AND SEE FOR YOURSELF.
FOR MULTI GRAIN FLAKES TT ARE
ANXCELLENT SOURCE OF FIBER
TRY GREAT GRAINS
BANANA NUT CRUNCH
AND CRANBERRY ALMOND CRUNCH.
>> Bill: I MENTIONED EARLIER
THAT THE SCHOOL HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, KINDERGARTEN
THROUGH FOURTH GRADE IN HAD A
LOCKDOWN PROCEDURE WHERE THE
SCHOOL WENT IN LOCKDOWN MODE AT
9:30 EVERY MORNING.
THAT'S IN THE COUNTRY SIDE.
THIS IS CONSIDERED SMALL TOWN
AMERICA, POPULATION 27,000.
SO THIS WEEKEND SCHOOL
OFFICIALS, YOU CAN IMAGINE, ALL
ACROSS THE COUNTRY ARE TAKING A
LOOK AT THEIR OWN SECURITY
PROCEDURES AND THE AFTERMATH OF
THE SHOOTING HERE IN NEWTOWN.
LAUREN WORKED WITH FOX AUSTIN IN
TEXAS.
SHE HAS A BIT MORE ON THAT
TONIGHT FOR US.
>> WHEN A GUNMAN WALKS INTO AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, IT'S OUR
WEAKEST POINT IN OUR SOCIETY.
>> Rick: TERRY NICHOLS IS THE
LAW ENFORCEMENT RAPID RESPONSE
TRAINING OR ALERT CENTER AT
TEXAS STATE UNIVERSITY.
HE'S KEEPING A CLOSE EYE ON THE
COVERAGE OF THE MASS SCHOOL
SHOOTING IN CONNECTICUT.
>> WE CAN DO EVERYTHING RIGHT.
TEACHERS CAN DO EVERYTHING
RIGHT, THE SCHOOL DISTRICT CAN
HAVE ALL THE PLANS IN THE WORLD.
LAW ENFORCEMENT CAN BE THERE
WITHIN SECONDS AND WE CAN STILL
HAVE A VERY, VERY SIGNIFICANT
BODY COUNT.
>> BUT HE AND OTHER ACTIVE
SHOOTER RESPONSE EXPERT ALSO
ANALYZE EVERY PART OF THIS
SITUATION AND TAKE A LOOK AT
THEIR TRAINING PROCEDURES.
>> IS THERE ANYTHING THAT WE CAN
TWEAK?
DO WE WORK CLOSE BETTER THE
SCHOOL DISTRICTS, WITH MODEL
POLICIES THROUGHOUT THE STANDARD
RESPONSE POETCAL?
>> IT WAS DEVELOPED BY A FATHER
WHO LOST HIS DAUGHTER IN A
COLORADO SCHOOL SHOOTING.
HIS PROTOCOL IS BEING ADOPTED BY
SCHOOL DISTRICTS AROUND THE
COUNTRY.
>> LOCKOUT, EVACUATE OR SHELTER.
FOUR SIMPLE TERMS THAT A
KINDERGARTENER CAN LEARN.
>> IS HE SAYS IT'S VITAL TO HAVE
THEM IN PLACE BECAUSE HOW
VULNERABLE PEOPLE ARE.
>> THEY HAVE PEOPLE CONFINED.
>> THIS INCIDENT WILL LIKELY
SPARK A CONVERSATION ABOUT WHAT
NEEDS TO CHANGE WHEN IT COMES TO
SCHOOL SECURITY.
>> IT'S JUST TRAGIC IF WE HAVE
TO FORTIFY OUR ELEMENTARY
SCHOOLS AND MAKE THEM LIKE A
FORTRESS.
OUR SOCIETY SHOULD NOT BE THAT
WAY.
>> Bill: THERE ARE A LOT OF
CONVERSATIONS LIKE THAT GOING ON
IN EVERY COMMUNITY THOUGHT THE
COUNTRY.
LAUREN, THANK YOU.
FOX AUSTIN, KTBC WITH A REPORT
THERE.
NOW WE WILL GET BACK TO THE
TRAGEDY HERE IN CONNECTICUT.
WE MAY HEAR FROM STATE POLICE
AGAIN LATER TONIGHT FOR MORE
INFORMATION ON WHERE IN THEIR
INVESTIGATION IT IS.
BUT FIRST THERE IS A CRITICAL
STORY DEVELOPING OVERSEAS IN
CAIRO, EGYPT, THROUGHOUT THE
COUNTRY OF EGYPT.
FOCUSLY DEFINING MOMENT FOR THAT
NATION AND FOR THE ENTIRE
REGION.
MILLIONS OF EGYPTIANS HEADED TO
THE POLLS TO DECIDE A
CONTROVERSIAL DRAFT
CONSTITUTION.
THAT VOTE THAT BEGINS THIS
WEEKEND COMES AFTER WEEKS OF
VIOLENT PROTESTS AGAINST WHAT
THE OPPONENTS CALL A CORRUPT
PROCESS AND A POWER GRAB BY THE
NEXT PRESIDENT WHO JUST TOOK THE
REINS, PRESIDENT MOHAMMED MORSI.
MUCH MORE ON THIS COMING UP IN A
LIVE REPORT.
GREG PALKOT IS BACK ON THE
GROUND IN CAIRO.
WE'LL TALK TO GREG THERE.
HERE IN NEWTOWN, A PLACE
RESIDENTS ARE PROUD, THEY ARE
PROUD TO CALL THIS PLACE HOME.
IN A MOMENT I'LL TALK LIVE WITH
ONE PERSON WHO LIVED HERE THEIR
ENTIRE LIFE ABOUT HOW THE
TRAGEDY IMPACTED HER AND HER
NEIGHBORS AS INVESTIGATORS START
PUTTING THE PIECES TOGETHER
[ sniffs ] I HAVE A COLD.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
>> Bill: THIS IS A COMMUNITY
THAT WILL COME TOGETHER IN WAYS
IT NEVER THOUGHT BEFORE EVEN
IMAGINABLE AS THEY GATHER IN
CHURCHES THROUGHOUT THE WEEKEND
DEALING WITH THE SHOCK OF WHAT
HAPPENED AT SANDY HOOK.
IT WAS SHOCK INITIALLY.
IT IS A STUNNED FEELING TODAY
AND I THINK IN SOME WAYS THAT
FEELING IS MOVING TOWARD ANGER,
FRANKLY.
WITH ME NOW IS THE WOMAN WHO
OWNS NEWTOWN'S BAGEL DELIGHT, A
MEMBER OF THIS COMMUNITY.
GOOD EVENING TO YOU.
>> GOOD EVENING.
>> Bill: I CERTAINLY WISH WE
WERE TALKING ABOUT OTHER
MATTERS.
BUT I APPRECIATE YOU SPENDING A
LITTLE TIME WITH US AND OUR
VIEWERS RIGHT NOW.
I UNDERSTAND THAT YOU KNEW
EVERYONE IN TOWN.
>> NOT EVERYONE, BUT --
>> Bill: THAT'S A HUGE
COMPLIMENT TO YOU.
WHAT IS THE SENSE ABOUT WHERE
THIS TOWN IS NOW ONLY A DAY AND
A HALF INTO THIS ENORMOUS
TRAGEDY?
>> WELL, AS EVERYONE KEEPS
SAYING, IT'S JUST SHOCKING.
NOTHING EVER HAPPENS IN NEWTOWN.
WE TALK ABOUT THE WEATHER AND
THE POSTPONEMENT OF THE LABOR
DAY PARADE BECAUSE OF THE
WEATHER.
BUT NOTHING OF THIS MAGNITUDE.
NOTHING THAT IS AS DEVASTATING
AS SHOCKING AS THIS.
TO THINK --
>> Bill: I UNDERSTAND YOU HELPED
PREPARE A MEAL FOR ONE OF THE
FAMILIES WHO LOST THEIR CHILD.
>> OH, YES.
>> Bill: I IMAGINE IN THE TIME
THAT YOU HAVE OWNED THAT
BUSINESS THAT THAT IS SOMETHING
YOU NEVER EVEN GAVE HALF A
THOUGHT TO.
>> OH, NOT AT ALL.
YOU WOULD JUST LIKE TO BRING
SOMETHING OVER TO EVERYONE THAT
HAS BEEN TOUCHED BY THIS.
PEOPLE ARE COMING IN, ASKING
WHAT THEY CAN DO IF THEY CAN
JUST BRING SOMETHING OR DO
SOMETHING, OR DOES ANYONE NEED A
RIDE OR DOES ANYONE NEED TO BE
PICKED UP.
ANYTHING THAT CAN BE DONE,
EVERYONE IS SAYING IT IS A
TIGHT-KNIT COMMUNITY THAT --
WE'RE ALL CONNECTED BY SOME WAY
OR MEANS.
AGAIN, IT'S JUST DEVASTATING.
>> Bill: NOW CONNECTED FOREVER
BY THIS TRAGEDY.
GOOD LUCK TO YOU AND YOUR
NEIGHBORS.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> Bill: THEY ARE SO KIND IN
THIS TOWN OF NEWTOWN AND EUNICE
IS A PERFECT EXAMPLE OF THAT.
WE HAVE MORE INFORMATION ON THE
INVESTIGATION.
WE HAVE MORE INFORMATION FOR THE
MEDICAL EXAMINERS.
OUR COVERAGE CONTINUES ON THE
SHOOTING IN SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE LATE INSIST ON THOSE 26
INNOCENT LIVES LOST AS WE
CONTINUE LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT TONIGHT, AS THE
SECOND HOUR OF OUR SPECIAL
COVERAGE GETS UNDERWAY RIGHT
AFTER THIS
There is no
mass-produced human.
So we created the
extraordinarily
comfortable Sleep Number
Experience.
around a bed with DualAir
Technology that allows you
to adjust to the support
your body needs - each of
your bodies.
Our sleep professionals will
help you find
your sleep number setting.
Exclusively at a Sleep
Number store.
Sleep Number.
Comfort individualized.
This holiday season, give
the gift that's magical:
the innovative AirFit
adjustable pillow at
special 30% savings.