ON HIS SHOES HE WILL BE BURIED
WITH A JERSEY NUMBER 80.
NOW MEANS SO MUCH.
ONE OF THE GOOD NEWS STORIES IN
SPORTS.
WHAT A GOOD INSPIRATION FOR THE
KIDS.
>> REMEMBER I TOLD YOU GOVERNOR
NIKKI HALEY SOUTH CAROLINA SHE
GOT TO APPOINT SOMEBODY TO
SENATOR DEMINT'S SPEECH SHE HAS
CHOSEN BILL SCOTT WHO IS A
FRESHMAN.
HE WILL BE SOUTH CAROLINA'S
FIRST BLACK SENATOR AND THE ONLY
AFRICAN AMERICAN SENATOR IN THE
UNITED STATES SENATE AT THIS
TIME.
ALL OF THE VICTIM'S FAMILIES
HEARTFELT FEELINGS FROM US
TONIGHT.
THAT'S IT FOR THE 5.
THANK YOU.
>>> WELCOME TO "RED EYE."
I'M ANDY LEVY IN FOR GREG
GUTFELD.
>> COMING UP, THE MASS
SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT RENEWED DED DEBATE
ABOUT GUN CONTROL AND
ENTERTAINMENT CULTURE.
OUR PANEL WILL DISCUSS.  ROB
PARKER HAS BEEN SUSPENDED
UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE FOR
DESCRIBING REDSKINS QB ROBERT
GRIFFIN THE THIRD BAYOUSING A
TERM I HAVE NEVER -- BY USING
A TERM I HAVE NEVER HEARD OF,
BIT I'M SURE IT WAS INPROP
RETE.
-- APPROPRIATE.
AND THE SUPREME COURT RULED ON
WHETHER BLARING LOUD MUSIC
FROM THE BACK OF YOUR CAR IS
INAPPROPRIATE.
APPARENTLY IT IS.
>> LET'S WELCOME OUR GUESTS.
JED DOJEDEDIAH BILA.
JIM NORTON.
HIS LATEST COMEDY CD CAME
OUTLAST WEEK CALLED "NO BABY
FOR YOU."
BILL SCHULZ, SORRY.
AND SITTING NEXT TO ME IS JOHN
BOLTON, FORMER U.S. AMBASSADOR
TO THE U.N AND FOX NEWS
CONTRIBUTOR.
WE WILL GET TO THE TOP STORY
TONIGHT.
HE SHUN ATTENTION UNTIL HE
DIDN'T.
ADAM LANZA WAS AN AWKWARD
LOANER WHO PRESSED HIMSELF
AGAINST THE WALL WHEN OTHERS
APPROACHED IN THE HALLWAY.
NOW A SHATTERED AND DEVASTATED
TOWN IS TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
WHY HE SLAUGHTERED HIS MOTHER
AND 26 OTHER ADULTS.
HE HAD PROBLEMS, PROBLEMS THAT
WENT BEYOND LACK OF SOCIAL
SKILLS.
THEY ASSIGNED HIM A PERMANENT
PSYCHOLOGIST AS A 9th
GRADER AND FLAGGED HIM TO THE
SECURITY CHIEF.
HE WAS MENTALLY ILL, CLEARLY,
AND THERE WERE REPORTS HE HAD
ASPBUREGER'S A MILDER FORM OF
AUTISM.
BUT WE DON'T KNOW EVERYTHING.
BUT IT HAS PUT THE SPOTLIGHT
ON MENTAL HEALTH.
AS ONE PSYCHOLOGIST TOLD USA
TODAY, IF WE WILL FOCUS ON
PREVENTION, WE CAN'T THINK OF
THE GUNMAN IN THE PARKING LOT
AND WHAT TO DO WITH THEM.
WE HAVE TO GET INVOLVED A LOT
EARLIER.
JIM, SO THIS GUY WAS AN
AWKWARD LONER AND PAINFULLY
QUIET.
SO ARE A LOT OF TEENAGERS.
HOW DO YOU DIFFERENTIATE?
CAN YOU?
>> YOU JUST KNOW.
WE ARE TAUGHT TO BE POLITE.
I LOVE HOW THEY SAY YOU CAN'T
JUDGE A BOOK BY THE COVER.
EVERY TIME I SEE A SCHOOL
SHOOTER HE LOOKS LIKE A SCHOOL
SHOOTER LOOKS.
THEY HAVE THE SAME STUPID
VACANT LOOK.
THEY GIVE YOU THE CREEPS, BUT
YOU ARE TAUGHT NOT TO TREAT
THEM LIKE THAT.
SOMEBODY GIVES YOU THE CREEPS
AND IT IS BECAUSE THEY ARE
CREEPY.
I DON'T KNOW WHY HE DID IT,
BUT HE IS A PSYCHO PATH.
THAT'S WHY HE DID IT.
WHY DID THE KILLER KILL?
BECAUSE HE IS INSANE.
YOU ARE NEVER GOING TO FIND A
REASON THAT MAKES SENSE OR
MAKES IT ACCEPTABLE OR MAKES
IT LESS RANDOM.
I AM JUST TIRED OF OBSESSING
ON WHY THE MENTALLY ILL DO
WHAT THEY DO.
>> JEDEDIAH, GOOD POINT, BUT
PSYCHOLOGISTS SAY THE
PERPETRATORS OF MASS MURDERS
OF VIRGINIA TECH AND OTHER
THINGS ALL SUFFERED FROM
SERIOUS MENTAL ISSUES AS JIM
WAS SAYING.
CAN WE FOCUS MORE ATTENTION ON
THESE PEOPLE AND TRY TO HEAD
THIS STUFF OFF AT THE PASS?
>> I THINK WE NEED TO FIGURE
OUT WHAT IS GOING ON AND WHY
THESE MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES ARE
GOING UNADDRESSED.
IT IS THE JOB OF A
PSYCHOLOGIST TO SEE WHY THEY
POSE A THREAT.
IF THEY ARE DOING THEIR JOB
THEY CAN DISTINGUISH BETWEEN
THE PEOPLE WHO ARE LOANERS AND
A LITTLE ODD VERSUS PEOPLE WHO
ARE DANGEROUS.
ANOTHER QUESTION I HAVE WAS
WAS HE ON MEDICATION?
A LOT OF THESE MEDICATIONS
USED TO TREAT DEPRESSION,
ANXIETY AND ADD HAVE SERIOUS
SIDE AFFECTS THAT COULD
POTENTIALLY MAKE YOU HAVE
OUTBURSTS AND MAKE A SIDE OF
YOUR PERSONALITY COME OUT YOU
DIDN'T KNOW EXISTED.
I HAVE SEEN THIS WITH KIDS IN
SCHOOLS WHERE THEIR
PERSONALITY CHANGES AS RESULT
OF MEDICATION.
I AM NOT SAYING THAT IS THE
SOLE CAUSE, BUT COULD BE A
CONTRIBUTING FACTOR.
>> AT THIS JUNCTURE WE DON'T
KNOW.
>> WE DON'T KNOW.
I'M SAYING THAT'S ONE OF THE
QUESTIONS THE REPORTERS SHOULD
BE ASKING.
WAS HE ON MED?
>> SOME STATES HAVE THE
ASSISTED OUTPATIENT TREATMENT
LAWS THAT ALLOW JUDGES TO
ORDER PEOPLE WITH A SERIOUS
MENTAL ILLNESS TO GO INTO
TREATMENT.
THE THING IS THESE PROGRAMS
ONLY APPLY TO PEOPLE WITH A
HISTORY OF VIOLENCE OR HAVE
BEEN INCARCERATED OR
HOSPITALIZED.
WE DON'T EVEN KNOW IF THAT
WOULD HAVE HELPED HERE.
IS THERE ANYTHING -- WHAT DO
YOU THINK?
>> I THINK WE NEED TO HAVE A
DISCUSSION ABOUT THE
PROTECTION THAT'S BEEN PUT
AROUND MENTAL ILLNESS.
IN MANY RESPECTS FOR GOOD
REASONS.
IT IS NOT THE PERSON'S FAULT
IF THEY SUFFER FROM SOME
EMOTIONAL DISTURBANCE.
IT IS A DISEASE.
JUST BECAUSE YOU DON'T WANT TO
STIGMA TIES THEM FOR SOMETHING
BEYOND THEIR CONTROL DOESN'T
MEAN YOU SHOULD HAVE A
HANDS-OFF ATTITUDE.
THIS IS NOT LIKE HAVING A
FLU.
THIS IS POTENTIALLY MUCH MORE
SERIOUS.
I THINK THAT THE NOTION THAT
BECAUSE MENTAL ILLNESS IS
STILL SOMETHING WE ARE TRYING
TO UNDERSTAND YOU HAVE TO
LEAVE PEOPLE ALONE UNTIL A
TRAGEDY HAPPENS IS JUST THE
WRONG WAY TO LOOK AT IT.
>> THE THING IS YOU CAN HELP
PEOPLE WITHOUT STIGMA TIEING
THEM.
>> I THINK THE EARLIER YOU
HAVE A SERIOUS CONVERSATION
ABOUT THIS POTENTIAL AND
CONSIDER INVOLUNTARY -- THIS
IS A SERIOUS PROBLEM.
I THINK THE LIBERTARIANS
UNDERSTANDABLY ARE WORRIED
ABOUT IT.
MASS MURDER IS A WORSE
PROBLEM.
>> SO, BILL, THE SCHOOL
OFFICIALS WHERE LANZA WENT TO
SCHOOL, THEY HAD HIM JOIN A
TECH CLUB THING.
IT IS TO HELP HIM TRY TO BE
MORE SOCIAL.
APPARENTLY IT DIDN'T HELP.
PEOPLE ARE ASKING SHOULD THE
SCHOOL HAVE DONE MORE?
CAN THE SCHOOL DO MORE?
IS THIS ULTIMATELY NOT THE
SCHOOL'S RESPONSIBILITY?
>> I DON'T KNOW IF IT IS THE
SCHOOL'S RESPONSIBILITY OR
NOT.
I DON'T KNOW HOW SOCIAL YOU
CAN BE IN A TECH CLUB.
YOU ALSO HAVE TO WONDER HOW
MUCH IS TOO MUCH AS FAR AS
THIS COVERAGE IS CONCERNED?
DILUTION AND NARCISSISM ARE IN
THE SAME BALLPARK.
A LOT OF THESE KIDS JUST NEED
A PUSH.
I WAS LOOKING AT A TABLOID
THIS WEEKEND, A NEW YORK
TABLOID, 20 PAGES OF COVERAGE
DEVOTED TO THIS.
THE SPORTS SECTION 10.
AFTER AWHILE, YOU HAVE TO
WONDER HOW MUCH IS TOO MUCH AS
FAR AS THIS COVERAGE IS
CONCERNED.
ALL OF THESE KIDS HAVE
DILUTIONS OF GRAND DURE.
IN RAPE CASES THEY AGREE NEVER
TO MENTION THE THAIM OF THE
VICTIM.
MAYBE SOMETHING LIKE THAT CAN
BE APPLIED TO THE PERPETRATOR
WHEN SOMETHING COMES TO THIS.
THESE KIDS ARE ALL ON THE
EDGE.
ALL IT TAKES IS A LITTLE
PUSH.
A LOT OF TIMES THEY SEE A
COHORT OR SOMEBODY WHO DID
SOMETHING THAT MAYBE HAS
CROSSED THEIR MIND AND THEN
THEY MENTION HIS NAME ONE
AFTER ANOTHER AFTER ANOTHER.
IN THEIR MIND THIS IS NOT A
BAD WAY TO GET THEIR NAME
OUT.
THERE IN THEIR MIND IT IS
LIKE -- WOW IF THIS GUY IS
GOING THIS WAY, WHY CAN'T I BE
THERE?
HAVE THE NOTORIATY I FEEL I
DESERVE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THE ANSWER
IS, BUT IT IS A LOT.
>> I THINK THERE IS A LOT TO
THIS.
ONE REASON THE MEDIA DON'T
BROADCAST TERRORIST DEMANDS OR
READ TERRORIST MAN FESS TOES
IS THEY DON'T WANT TO
ENCOURAGE OTHER TERRORISTS.
IN THE PECULIAR WAY I THINK
THE MINDS OF SOME OF THESE
PEOPLE WORK, THEY SEE THIS AS
A WAY TO GET PUBLICITY.
IF YOU ARE A LONER AND DON'T
THINK ANYBODY PAYS ATTENTION
TO YOU OR CARES YOU OR LOVES
YOU, AND YET YOU SEE WHAT
HAPPENS WITH THIS OBSESSIVE
COVERAGE, I THINK IT IS OVER
THE TOP FOR MANY REASONS.
BUT ITS POTENTIAL IMPACT OF
PEOPLE WHO COULD GO OVER THE
EDGE IS SOMETHING THE MEDIA
NEED TO HAVE A CONVERSATION
ABOUT INSTEAD OF BLAMING OTHER
PEOPLE.
THIS IS SOMETHING THE MEDIA
CAN AFFECT ITSELF.
>> JIM, I KNOW YOU HAVE STRONG
FEELINGS ABOUT IT AND WE
TALKED ABOUT IT IN THE GREEN
ROOM, AND YOU PRETTY MUCH
AGREE WITH THEM.
LET ME BRING THIS UP THOUGH,
THE MEDIA COVERS SADDAM
HUSSEIN.
THE MEDIA COVERS CRAZY
DICTATORS.
WE DO COVER PEOPLE LIKE THAT
BECAUSE IT IS NEWSWORTHY.
HOW DO YOU SAY, WELL YOU
SHOULDN'T COVER THIS WHEN IT
IS CLEARLY NEWSWORTHY?
>> WELL, SADDAM HUSSEIN, YOU
ARE NOT GOING TO INSPIRE OTHER
PEOPLE TO BECOME A DICTATOR BY
COVERING SADDAM HUSSEIN.
YOU HAVE TO COVER IT BECAUSE
IT IS LEGITIMATE NEWS, AND WE
WANT TO KNOW WHAT IS GOING
ON.
BUT THERE BECOMES A POINT
WHERE IT IS TABLOID AND
DISGUSTING.
THE MEDIA KNOWS WHERE THAT
LINE IS.
PSYCHOLOGISTS HAVE BEEN
TELLING THEM FOR YEARS HOW TO
COVER THIS STORY.
THEY ARE NOT NAIVE.
WE HAVE THE SAME BORING GUN
DISCUSSIONS.
>> IS IT MENTAL ILLNESS OR
GUNS?
THE MEDIA NEVER HAS A
DISCUSSION, WHAT DID WE DO TO
CONTRIBUTE?
WHEN THE SHOOTING HAPPENED IN
AURORA YOU KNEW MORE WERE
COMING.
THEY ARE GIVING THESE WORMS
WHAT THEY WANT.
THEY LET THEM GO OUT IN A
BLAZE OF GLORY, AND THE PRESS
KNOW THEY ARE DOING IT, AND
THEY DON'T CARE.
DON'T LET THEM FEIGN
IGNORANCE.
WE ARE JUST DOING OUR JOB.
THEY KNOW AND THEY ADD
ADMONISH THEMSELVES OF GUILT
BECAUSE THEY FEEL THEY CAN
HIDE BEHIND DOING THEIR JOB.
DISGUSTING.
>>> GEDS DO DYE YAW WE WILL --
JEDEDIAH WE ARE TALKING ABOUT
GUNS IN A MINUTE.
I WANT TO STAY ON THIS MENTAL
HEALTH THING FOR A SECOND.
I KNOW A LITTLE ABOUT GUNS.
I SAW A LOT OF FLAT OUT WRONG
INFORMATION BEING PASSED
AROUND ON TWITTER AND NEWS
REPORTS, STUFF ABOUT AUTOMATIC
WEAPONS AND PEOPLE NOT
UNDERSTANDING WHAT A
SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPON IS
APPARENTLY.
SO TO GET BACK TO MENTAL
HEALTH, MOST OF THE PEOPLE WHO
ARE TALKING ABOUT THAT
INCLUDING US RIGHT HERE AREN'T
EXPERTS.
WE PROBABLY DON'T KNOW WHAT
THE HELL WE ARE TALKING ABOUT,
RIGHT 1234*.
>> WHEN IT COMES TO MENTAL
HEALTH YOU NEED MENTAL HEALTH
EXPERTS TO BE TALKING.
TO FOX NEWS' CREDIT YOU HAVE A
LOT OF DOCTORS ON THAT WERE
DISCUSSING THE IMPLICATIONS TO
THE FACT THIS COULD HAVE FOR
KIDS WHO SURVIVED AND HOW THE
SITUATION SHOULD BE DEALT WITH
AND HOW IT SHOULD BE EXPLAINED
TO YOUR CHILDREN IF YOU
WEREN'T INVOLVED AND WE HAD A
CROWD HAMMER ON.
IT WAS THE FIRST PERSON WHO WE
SAID WE NEED TO GET INTO THE
MINDS OF THESE PEOPLE.
WE NEED TO ADDRESS THE MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUE.
TO YOUR QUESTION BEFORE ABOUT
SCHOOLS AND HOW MUCH THEY CAN
DO, WE HAVE TO REMEMBER THAT
THIS IN MANY CASES RESIDES
WITH PARENTS.
THOSE ARE THE PEOPLE WHO ARE
WITH THESE KIDS 24-7.
THESE ARE THE PEOPLE WHO ARE
IN AN AUTHORITATIVE POSITION
WHERE THEY CAN MAKE THESE
DECISIONS ABOUT WHAT KIND OF
HELP THEIR KIDS GET.
AT A CERTAIN POINT THE SCHOOL
DOES LEGALLY NEED TO STEP BACK
AND SAY THIS IS THE JOB OF
PARENTS.
>> I WANT TO-ON TO GUNS.
SUNDAY NIGHT'S VIGIL AND
PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID HE WOULD
ENTER THE DEBATE IN GUN
CONTROL IN THE WEEKS TO COME.
>> NO SINGLE LAW, NO SET OF
LAWS CAN ELIMINATE EVIL FROM
THE WORLD OR PREVENT EVERY
SENSELESS ACT OF VIOLENCE IN
OUR SOCIETY, BUT THAT CAN'T BE
AN EXCUSE FOR AN ACTION.
SURELY WE CAN DO BETTER THAN
THIS.
IN THE COMING WEEKS I WILL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE
HOLDS TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW
CITIZENS FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT
TO MENTAL HEALTH PROFESSIONALS
TO PARENTS AND EDUCATORS IN AN
EFFORT AIMED AT PREVENTING
MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS.
>> ON MONDAY WHITE HOUSE PRESS
SECRETARY JAY CARNEY SAYS THE
ISSUE WILL REQUIRE A, QUOTE,
COMPREHENSIVE SOLUTION, END
QUOTE INVOLVING GUN CONTROL
AND OTHER MEASURES.
AND DIANNE FEINSTEIN HAS SAID
SHE WILL INTRODUCE A DE PHAK
TOE RENEWAL OF THE BAN EXPIRED
IN 2004.
REPUBLICAN CONGRESSMAN NOTED
ON FOX NEWS SUNDAY THAT
STRICTER GUN CONTROL DOES NOT
NECESSARILY MEAN THAT CRIME
RATES GO DOWN.
>> WASHINGTON, D.C. SHOULD BE
THE SAFEST PLACE IN AMERICA,
IT IS NOT.
IG CHICAGO SHOULD BE SAFE.
THEIR GUN LAWS DON'T WORK.
>> AMBASSADOR ON MONDAY, THE
SENATOR WHO IS AN AVID -- I'M
SORRY, DEMOCRAT WHO IS AN AVID
HUNTER AND NRA MEMBER.
HE SAID GUN CONTROL
LEGISLATION SHOULD BE -- NEEDS
TO BE PART OF A DISCUSSION.
HAVE WE -- ARE WE SEE A SHIFT
IN THE GUN CONTROL DEBATE IN
THE TONE AT LEAST?
>> IT IS TOO EARLY TO TELL.
I THINK ALL OF THESE ISSUES
NEED TO BE DEBATED.
BUT MANY OF THE PEOPLE WHO ARE
NOW SAYING, SEE THIS PROVES
YOU NEED STRONGER GUN CONTROL
LAWS HELD THAT POSITION BEFORE
THE NEWTOWN MASACRE AND FOR
VARIOUS THRANS HAVE NOTHING TO
DO WITH WHAT HAPPENED THERE.
IF YOU CHANGE THE EXISTING GUN
CONTROL LAWS, WOULD IT HAVE
STOPPED NEWTOWN OR AURORA?
THE ANSWER IN MOST CASES IS
NO.
I THINK THAT TIES IN PART TO
THE POINT YOU MADE ABOUT
PEOPLE NOT REALLY
UNDERSTANDING THE NATURE OF
THESE WEAPONS.
YOU CALL SOMETHING
SEMIAUTOMATIC.
THAT SOUNDS LIKE ALMOST
AUTOMATIC.
I HAVEN'T FIRED A
AUTOMATIC SINCE I WAS ON
ACTIVE DUTY.
MOST OF THE PEOPLE WHO TALK
ABOUT IT HAVE NEVER DONE IT.
IF YOU HAVE EVER DONE IT ONCE
YOU KNOW WHAT IT MEANS.
I THINK ALSO IT GOES TO THIS
QUESTION OF DEFENSE.
YOU CAN'T LOCK UP ALL OF THE
EMOTIONALLY DISTURBED PEOPLE.
YOU CAN'T GET RID OF ALL OF
THE GUNS.
YOU WILL ALWAYS HAVE THE
POTENTIAL.
WHAT STEPS TO PROTECT THE
SCHOOLS ARE YOU TAKING?
TO DECLARE THEM GUN FREE ZONES
MEANING THE TEACHERS DON'T
HAVE GUNS AND THAT SECURITY
JUST HOPE OPS THEM -- JUST
OPENS THEM UP TO THIS KIND OF
ATTACK.
>> I WANT TO QUOTE THE SENATOR
AGAIN SAYING I DON'T KNOW
ANYBODY THAT GOES OUT WITH AN
ASSAULT RIFLE OR ANYBODY THAT
NEEDS 30 ROUNDS IN A CLIP TO
GO HUNTING.
I FIND IT ODD THAT AN AVID
HUNTER WOULD CONFUSE A CLIP
AND A MAGAZINE, BUT THAT'S A
SEPARATE ISSUE.
DO YOU AGREE WITH HIM THOUGH?
DOES HE HAVE A POINT?
>> YOU NEED TO KEEP IN MIND
THAT ADAM LANZA TRIED TO BUY A
LEGAL GUN AND WAS DENIED.
HE REFUSED THE BACK GROUND
CHECK.
HE REFUSED TO GO IN THE
WAITING PERIOD.
HE DIDN'T GET A LEGAL GUN.
450E STOLE SOMEBODY ELSE'S
GUN.
THE GUN CONTROL LAW THAT
PREVENTED HIM FROM GETTING A
LEGAL GUN WORKED.
WHAT DIDN'T WORK WAS THE FACT
THAT HE STOLE SOMEBODY ELSE'S
GUN.
THERE IS NOTHING YOU CAN DO
ABOUT THAT.
IF A CRAZY PERSON WILL STEEL
SOMEBODY ELSE'S GUN, ODDS ARE
THEY WILL GET IT.
AND THE SCHOOL RKS GUN FREE
ZONE.
ALL OF THESE PLACES, THE WILL
MAS, THE MOVIE THEATERS THESE
PEOPLE GO TO ARE GUN FREE
ZONES FOR A REASON.
THEY KNOW PEOPLE WON'T BE
ARMED TO PROTECT THEMSELVES.
>> YOU COULD ARGUE THAT IF HIS
MOTHER HADN'T BEEN ALLOWED TO
PURCHASE THE GUN HE WOULDN'T
HAVE BEEN ABLE TO STEEL IT
FROM HER.
>> YOU COULD, BUT THAT'S LIKE
SAYING EVERY PERSON WHO IS A
LAW ABIDING CITIZEN HAS TO BE
PUNISHED AND CAN'T PROTECT
THEMSELVES BECAUSE SOMEONE
ELSE WHO ISN'T A LAW ABIDING
CITIZEN MAY DECIDE TO STEAL
THEIR STUFF.
>> ISN'T THAT GUN CONTROL?
>>-
>> SHOULD HIS MOTHER BE MORE
CAREFUL WITH SOMEBODY IN THE
HOUSE, WE DON'T KNOW.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT SAFETY
PRECAUTIONS THERE WERE TO KEEP
THE GUNS OUT OF HIS HAND.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT WAS GOING
IN TERMS OF THE FAMILY
DYNAMIC.
I WOULD ARGUE, YES, IF YOU
HAVE A CHILD WITH MENTAL
ISSUES WHO IS TEETERING ON THE
EDGE AND YOU HAVE GUNS IN THE
HOUSEHOLD, IT IS YOUR
RESPONSIBILITY TO MAKE SURE
THE GUNS ARE PROTECTED.
>> WHAT ABOUT THE IDEA THAT
SCHOOL OFFICIALS SHOULD BE
ARMED?
SOME PEOPLE ARE SAYING THIS
NOW.
IS THIS OVERREACTING?
THE FACT IS SCHOOLS ARE AMONG
SAFEST PLACES FOR KIDS.
>> IF YOU ARM THE SCHOOL
OFFICIALS, ONE OF THEM IS
GOING TO SNAP.
OH WE HAVE TO ARM THE
CAFETERIA LADIES.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
WHO EVER HAS IT, IF ONE OF
THAT GROUP SNAPS PEOPLE SAY OH
MY GOD.
IT IS LIKE NOTHING -- IT
DOESN'T CHANGE ANYBODY'S
OPINION.
WHEN SOMETHING LIKE THIS
HAPPENS, PEOPLE WHO ARE VERY,
VERY FOR GUNS IT STRENGTHENS
THEIR OPINIONS.
IF I TWHRAS WITH MY GUN I
WOULD HAVE STOPPED IT.
PEOPLE ANTI-GUNS SAY LOOK SEE
WHAT HAPPENS.
IT IS A TALKING POINT PEOPLE
USE TO STRENGTHEN THEIR SIDE
OF THE ARGUMENT.
IT CHANGES NOTHING.
>> IN THE CASE OF THE SCHOOL
ATTACK THE PRINCIPAL AND OTHER
TEACHERS VERY COURAGEOUSLY
WENT TOWARD THE GUNMAN IN AN
EFFORT TO PROTECT THE CHILDREN
AND DIED AS A RESULT OF THEIR
COURAGE.
HAD THEY HAD WEAPONS WOULD THE
RESULT HAVE BEEN DIFFERENT?
IT IS HARD TO IMAGINE IT COULD
HAVE BEEN WORSE THAN
26-YEAR-OLDS BEING KILLED.
I THINK THE POSSIBILITY WITH
TRAINING AND WITH SUPERVISION
I THINK WOULD POSSIBLY DETER
PEOPLE LIKE THE NEWTOWN.
>> DO WE REQUIRE THAT
PRINCIPALS AND TEACHERS GET
GUN SAFETY TRAINING?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
I THINK THIS OUGHT TO BE PART
OF THE DEBATE.
THE NOTION OF THE GUN FREE
ZONE ZONE -- MAYBE YOU DON'T
WANT YOUR STUDENTS TO HAVE
GUNS, BUT THAT DOESN'T MEAN
YOU DON'T WANT SOME SYSTEM OF
SECURITY GUARD FOR EXAMPLE TO
PROTECT THE STUDENTS.
THIS LANZA COMMITTED SUICIDE
WHEN HE KNEW THE POLICE HAD
ARRIVED.
WHY?
THEY WERE THE PEOPLE WITH THE
GUNS.
THAT'S WHAT HE FEARED.
>> FROM YOU A COP OR MILITARY
GUY --
>> ARE YOU TALKING AN AIR
MARTIAL SYSTEM?
>> SOMEBODY THERE WHO IS USED
TO -- EVEN A TEACHER WITH A
GUN AND BEING WELL
INTENTIONED, BEING TRAINED
WITH A GUN IS ONE THING, BUT
RUNNING IN WHEN THERE IS A
MANIAC FIRING IS TOTALLY
DIFFERENT.
>> COULD NOT AGREE MORE.
BILL, I SAW A QUOTE THAT SAID
THIS IS GOING TO BE THE
EQUIVALENT OF SCHOOLS THAT
9/11 WAS FOR AIRPORTS.
IS THAT WHAT WE WANT?
DO WE WANT THE EQUIVALENT OF A
TSA IN SCHOOLS?
>> WHAT MORE CAN THEY DO AT
THIS POINT?
I CAN'T SPEAK SPECIFICALLY TO
WHAT THE SCHOOL WAS DOING, BUT
WEREN'T THEY AT THE TOP OF THE
LIST WHEN IT COMES TO SAFE
SCHOOLS?
THEY HAD LOCKED DOORS AND ALL
KINDS OF SECURITY PROVISIONS.
HE STORMED HIS WAY IN.
AT THIS POINT IF IT IS GOING
TO HAPPEN, IT IS GOING TO
HAPPEN.
THE THING I HAVE SEEN A LITTLE
BIT OF HERE IS I DON'T
UNDERSTAND WHEN PEOPLE START
EQUATING GUN CONTROL WITH
BANNING GUNS.
THAT ALWAYS SEEMS TO BE THE
PARALLEL I SEE MADE.
ONE IS COMPLETELY DIFFERENT
FROM THE OTHER.
YOU FIND A LOT OF GUN OWNERS
ARE COMPLETELY FOR COMMON
SENSE MOVEMENTS THAT INVOLVE
GUN CONTROL.
IT SEEMS THE ARGUMENT STOPS
WHEN YOU MENTION THE WORDS
BECAUSE THAT IMMEDIATELY
EQUATES BACK, BACK, SECOND --
BAM, BAM, SECOND AMENDMENT.
HE DID A POLL AND HE ASKED THE
GUN OWNERS, NONNRA GUN OWNS
AND NRA GUN OWNERS IF THERE
SHOULD BE A REQUIRED
BACKGROUND CHECK ON OWNERS AND
EMPLOYEES.
MOST SAID YES.
CONCEALED CARRY PERMITS SHOULD
ONLY BE GIVEN TO THOSE WHO
COMPLETED A SAFETY COURSE.
MOST SAID YES.
THERE IS A CONSENSUS HERE.
WHAT YOU DON'T HEAR ARE THESE
PEOPLE.
YOU HEAR THE REPRESENTATIVES
OF THE NRA AND FAR RIGHT
POLITICAL STRATEGISTS,
WHATEVER THAT MEANS.
ON TV DOING THEIR AGENDA.
THE FACT OF THE MATTER IS
THERE ARE LESS PEOPLE BUYING
GUNS NOW.
THERE ARE MORE PEOPLE BUYING A
LOT OF GUNS, BUT GUN OWNERSHIP
IN HOUSEHOLDS HAS GONE DOWN
BIG TIME.
THEY HAVE TO KEEP THE NUMBERS
UP JIE. LET ME TAKE THE OTHER
SIDE OF THIS.
THIS IS SOMETHING I SAW OVER
THE WEEKEND ON TV OR TWITTER,
ALL OF THESE PEOPLE SAYING WE
NEED TO HAVE A CONVERSATION ON
GUN CONTROL.
IT IS TIME FOR A CONVERSATION.
BY ALL MEANS, LET'S HAVE A
CONVERSATION.
BUT MOST OF THESE PEOPLE DON'T
WANT A CONVERSATION.
A CONVERSATION REQUIRES
LISTENING TO PEOPLE WHO
DISAGREE WITH YOU.
AND IT IS STARTING FROM THE
PREMISE THAT BOTH SIDES ARE
COMING FROM BOOTH FAITH.
-- COMING FROM GOOD FAITH.
THEY DON'T WANT A
CONVERSATION.
THEY WANT GUN CONTROL.
>> THEY WANT TO TALK ABOUT
WHAT THEY FEEL.
THE BOTTOM LINE IS THE STATS
IF YOU LOOK AROUND THE
COUNTRY, THE STATES, THE
CITIES, IT IS PLACES WITH THE
STRICTEST GUN CONTROL LAWS
HAVE THE HIGHEST CRIME
LEVELS.
IT IS A DETERRENT FOR
CRIMINALS.
THINK ABOUT IT.
IF YOU HAD A SECURITY GUARD
PROTECTING YOU ALL DAY AND I
THREW THIS OUT TO PIERCE
MORGAN OR ONE OF THE MEDIA
FOLKS WOULD YOU WANT THEM
ARMED?
I WOULD IF I WAS OUT THERE AND
A HIGH PROFILE FIGURE I WOULD
WANT MY SECURITY TEAM ARMED.
IT MAKES NO SENSE.
>> WE HAVE TO MOVE ON.
A BIG THING GOING IS EVERYONE
SAYS IN THE WAKE OF THIS WE
HAVE TO DO SOMETHING, DO
SOMETHING.
I AM OPPOSED TO CALLING FOR
LEGISLATION AND PASSING
LEGISLATION IN THE HEAT OF THE
MOMENT WHEN EMOTIONS ARE
HIGH.
TO ME THAT'S HOW YOU END UP
WITH THINGS LIKE THE PATRIOT
ACT WHICH END UP HAVING A LOT
OF UNINTENDED CONSEQUENCES OR
INTENDED CONSEQUENCES THAT
PEOPLE DIDN'T QUITE REALIZE
WHEN THEY WERE VOTING FOR IT.
HAVE A CONVERSATION,
ABSOLUTELY.
WE DON'T NEED TO PASS ANYTHING
IN THE NEXT COUPLE DAYS OR
ANYTHING LIKE THAT.
COMING UP, A DIFFERENT STORY,
SOMETHING ABOUT FOOTBALL
PERHAPS.
YOU ARE WATCHING "RED EYE" ON
FNC.
STICK AROUND.
>>> IS IT CORNY IF RG3 LIKES
THE GSP?
THEY SUSPENDED ROB PARKER FOR
CALLING ROBERT GRIFFIN THE
THIRD A CORN BROTHER AND
SAYING HE SHOULD NOT BE JUDGED
ON THE BASIS OF RACE.
>> MY QUESTION WHICH IS A
STRAIGHT, HONEST QUESTION, IS
HE A BROTHER OR A CORNWALL
BROTHER?
>> WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
>> HE DOES THE THING, BUT SHE
NOT REALLY DOWN WITH THE
CAUSE.
HE IS NOT ONE OF US.
WE KNOW HE IS A REPUBLICAN AND
THERE IS NO INFORMATION AT
ALL.
I AM JUST TRYING TO DIG DEEPER
INTO WHY HE HAS AN ISSUE.
>> HERE IS STEVEN A SMITH
SUMMING UP THE SEGMENT
NICELY.
>> I AM UNCOMFORTABLE WITH
WHERE WE JUST WENT.
>> AND WHILE THE NETWORK
CONDUCTS A FULL REVIEW
WHATEVER THAT MEANS, PARKER
HAS CHASTISED CRITICS ON
TWITTER BY CALLING THEM,
QUOTE, UNEDUCATED.
THERE IS A BURN NOTICE IF I
EVER HEARD ONE.
AS FOR SANTA PAWS, STILL HATES
THE HOLIDAYS.
THE WAR ON CHRISTMAS GETS MORE
AND MORE VIOLENT.
JIM, I AM GUESSING REGARDLESS
OF WHAT YOU THINK ABOUT PARK
PARKER'S COMMENTS HE SHOULD
NOT HAVE BEEN SUSPENDED.
>> I AM QUIET ON THIS ONE.
I TYPICALLY HATE SEEING PEOPLE
SUSPENDED FOR EXPRESSING
THEMSELVES.
BUT IF IT WAS A WHITE
COMMENTATOR SAYING THAT HE
WOULD BE SUSPENDED.
FIRST OF ALL HIS HEAD IS AWFUL
TO LOOK AT.
I THOUGHT I HAD A MISS SHAPEN
HEAD.
THERE IS NOTHING MORE BORING
THAN WATCHING A GUY QUESTION
ANOTHER GUY'S RACIAL
ALLEGIANCE OR QUALIFICATION
IN, WHAT, 1970s THINK ?G HE
IS NOT BROTHER ENOUGH?
HE IS MARRIED TO A HONKEY?
>> LIKE THE JEFFERSONS.
>> THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT IT IS
LIKE.
I DON'T WANT TO SEE A GUY
FIRED ON THIS, BUT I HOPE HE
IS FIRED FOR SOMETHING ELSE.
>> THIS STEMS FROM RG3 SAYING,
LOOK, I DON'T WANT TO BE
DEFINED AS AN AFRICAN-AMERICAN
QUARTERBACK.
ISN'T THAT COMMON SENSE?
WOULD YOU RATHER BE KNOWN AS A
GREAT AFRICAN-AMERICAN
QUARTERBACK OR A GREAT
QUARTERBACK.
>> THIS IS A CRITICAL POINT
WHERE OUR SOCIETY HAS REVERSED
WHERE WE STARTED OUT IN THE
CIVIL RIGHTS MOVEMENT.
IT WAS MARTIN LUTHER KING WHO
SAID "I LOOK FORWARD TO A DAY
WHEN PEOPLE ARE JUDGED BY THE
CONTENT OF THEIR CHARACTER AND
NOT THE COLOR OF THEIR SKIN."
THEY OBVIOUSLY DIDN'T GET THE
MEMO AT ESPN.
UNFORTUNATELY IT IS TRUE
ACROSS THE BOARD.
THAT'S HOW WE CAMPAIGN IN
POLITICS.
AT LEAST THAT'S HOW THE OBAMA
CAMPAIGN WORKED.
YOU TARGET ETHNIC GROUPS,
RELIGIONS ON THE BASIS OF
GENDER.
YOU DON'T TALK ABOUT ISSUES.
I THINK IT IS DEMEANING.
I THINK PEOPLE ARE MULTI
DIMENSIONAL.
WHEN YOU TRY AND PIGEON HOLE
SOMEBODY AS THE BLACK GUY OR
THE WOMAN, YOU ARE GOING IN
THE WRONG DIRECTION.
>> JED JEDEDIAH, RG3 HAS
AMAZING LEGS AND ARM AND HE
WILL BE REMEMBERED LONG AFTER
ROB PARKER IS FORGOTTEN.
>> OH YES.
THIS GUY IS ALREADY OLD NEWS.
I DON'T KNOW WHY WE ARE
TALKING ABOUT HIM.
YOU KNOW, THIS GUY SAID
SOMETHING STUPID, PARKER.
YOU HAVE TO BE HELD
ACCOUNTABLE FOR WHAT YOU SAY.
AS I RECALL I THINK RUSH
LIMBAUGH SAID SOMETHING THAT
HAD RACIAL UNDERTONES YEARS
AGO ON ESPN, AND HE WAS FORCED
TO RESIGN.
I THINK ESPN WAS IN A TOUGH
SITUATION.
IF YOU ARE GOING TO HOLD
PEOPLE ACCOUNTABLE YOU HAVE TO
DO IT ACROSS THE BOARD AND
HAVE SOME CONSISTENCY.
>> LAST WORD TO YOU, QUICK.
>> I THINK RUSH LIMBAUGH
OFFENDED ALL BLACK PEOPLE.
THIS JUST OFFENDED CORN BALL
ONES.
THE FUNNY PART WAS ROB PARKER
GAVE HIM STREET CREDS.
I THINK HE IS NOT TRYING TO
LOOK LIKE A SURFER.
FAVORITE GROUP IS THE BEACH
BOYS, FACT.
>> DO YOU HAVE A COMMENT ON
THE SHOW?
E-MAIL AS YOU RED EYE AT FOX
NEWS.COM.
AND DO YOU HAVE VIDEO OF YOUR
ANIMAL DOING SOMETHING?
GO TO FOX NEWS.COM/RED EYE AND
CLICK ON SUBMIT A VIDEO.
WE MIGHT USE IT.
STILL TO COME, THE HALF TIME
REPORT FROM TOM SHILLOU.
>> TONIGHT'S HALF TIME REPORT
IS SPONSORED BY SLED DOGS.
THE DOGS TRAINED TO PULL A
SLED ESPECIALLY AS PART OF A
DOG TEAM.
THANKS, SLED DOGS.
>>> LET'S FIND OUT IF WE HAVE
GOTTEN ANYTHING WRONG.
WE GO TO TOM SHILLOU.
>> YES, YOU ARE.
I GOT THAT RIGHT.
THE MENTAL HEALTH DISCUSSION
AT THE BEGINNING.
JIM NORTON, YOU SAID YOU DON'T
CARE TO ASK, AND YOU KIND
OF -- YOU GAVE IT A LITTLE
VOICE SAYING WHO DID THE
KILLER KILL?
THIS IS WHAT HAVE YOU BEEN
HEARING ALL THE TIME.
WHY DID THE KILLER -- YOU ARE
SICK OF HEARING PEOPLE SAY WHY
DID THE KILLER KILL?
BUT IF THE ANSWER TO THAT
LEADS TO SOME KIND OF INITTER
VEPTION, VEPTION -- KIND OF
INTERVENTION COULD IT BE
AVAILABLE?
>> SURE, BUT IT TENDS TO LEAD
TO MORE MEDIA COVERAGE.
IT IS STAGE 3 OF THEM
PROSTITUTING A STORY, IS THIS
FEIGN INTEREST WHY DID THE
AURORA KILLER AND THEN THEY
CALL IT WHY DID THE JOKER
KILL?
AND I AM NEVER CONCERNED WITH
THE MOTIVES OF A SOCIOPATH.
IT IS NEVER GOING TO MAKE
SENSE.
THEY ARE NOT SO CRAZY THEY
DON'T KNOW WHAT THEY ARE
DOING.
HE PLANED IT AND SHOT HIMSELF
WHEN THE COPS ARE COMING.
HE KNEW THE CONSEQUENCES.
YOU ARE NEVER GO BE TO FIND AN
ANSWER THAT MAKES IT LESS
RANDOM AND LESS FRIGHTENING.
>> THAT'S A GOOD EXAMPLE.
WASN'T IT THE MOVIE THEATER
SHOOTER WHO WAS DRESSED LIKE A
SUPER VILLAIN?
>> YES.
OR GABBY GIFFORDS, THE GUY WHO
SHOT HER ISN'T THERE EVER GO
BE TO BE A TIME WHERE WE SAY
OH OKAY THAT MAKES SENSE.
NO, IT NEVER MAKES SENSE.
>> JEDEDIAH, YOU RESPONDED
SAYING THIS IS THE JOB OF A
PSYCHOLOGIST TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT MAKES THESE PEOPLE TICK.
THE QUESTION IS, IF WE DO FIND
A WAY TO ISOLATE THESE PEOPLE,
ISN'T THE ISSUE REALLY LESS
ABOUT PSYCHOLOGY AND MORE
ABOUT THE WILLINGNESS TO FORCE
THESE PEOPLE INTO TREATMENT?
WE DON'T SEEM TO BE ABLE TO
DO.
>> IF IT IS A MINOR YOU HAVE
TO DEAL WITH THE PARENTS AND
WORK WITH THEM.
THE IDEA IS TO FIGURE OUT IF
THESE PEOPLE ARE DANGEROUS
BEFORE THEY BECOME DANGEROUS
AND TO MONITOR.
LIKE I SAID IF THEY ARE ON
MEDICATIONS AND UNDER
TREATMENT AND TO MAKE SURE IF
THESE ARE YOUNG PEOPLE WHO ARE
LIVING WITH PARENTS OR HAVE
CLOSE RELATIVES THAT THERE IS
SOMEONE INVOLVED IN THE
SITUATION WHO IS AWARE OF THE
SEVERITY OF IT AND MONITORING
IT.
A LOT GOES UNMONITORED.
AND THEN IT IS TOO LATE.
WE LOOK AT THE NEWS STORIES
AND WE SEE THERE WERE ALL OF
THESE WARNING SIGNS, WHY
DIDN'T ANYONE DO ANYTHING
ABOUT IT?
MAYBE ENOUGH PEOPLE KNEW WHAT
WAS GOING.
>> YOU WERE A TEACHER, AM I
RIGHT?
>> I WAS A TEACHER AND A DEAN
AND AN ADVISOR.
>> THEY TALK ABOUT ARMING
PRINCIPALS.
DO YOU KNOW MANY PEOPLE IN
ADMINISTRATION WHO ARE WILLING
TO WALK AROUND ARMED?
IT DOESN'T SEEM LIKE THAT IS
THE CULTURE THAT ACCEPTS THIS
CHARACTER.
>> IT DEPENDS ON WHERE IT IS.
IN TEXAS MAYBE.
IN NEW YORK CITY PROBABLY
NOT.
I AM CONCERNED ABOUT THAT JUST
BECAUSE I KNOW WHAT DIFFICULT
SCHOOLS LOOK LIKE WHERE THERE
ARE VERY TOUGH KIDS.
I KNOW THERE IS TENSION IN
CLASSROOMS ALL OF THE TIME.
I WOULD BE A LITTLE WORRIED
ABOUT THE TEACHER BEING
WORRIED WHERE THE WEAPON WAS.
ALL OF THAT WORRIES ME.
I SUPPORT SECURITY AT SCHOOL.
IF YOU HAD A TRAINED
PROFESSIONAL WHO WAS VISIBLE
TO THE PUBLIC OUTSIDE AND IN
AND OUT.
IT WAS KNOWN AS A GROUND THAT
WAS PROTECTED BY SOMEONE WHO
WAS ARMED THAT COULD MAKE A
WORLD OF DIFFERENCE.
>> CERTAINLY PEOPLE ARE
COMFORTABLE IN OTHER
COUNTRIES.
SOMETIMES THERE ARE GUYS WITH
MACHINE GUNS OUTSIDE HOTELS.
>> AND GUESS WHAT, THE PEOPLE
IN THAT HOTEL ARE WELL
PROTECTED.
NO ONE IS GOING IN THERE TO
BOTHER THEM.
>> THAT'S THE TIME I FELT SAFE
IN MY HOTEL.
>> I HATE TO TELL YOU HOW TO
DO YOUR JOB, BUT WE ARE
BURYING THE LEAD.
HOW COME NO TEACHER WE EVER
HAD LOOKED LIKE JEDEDIAH.
>> I HAD A MALE TEACHER WHO
WORE THAT DRESS.
>> THAT'S WHY THEY PUT HER IN
THE FRONT OFFICE.
>> I DID HAVE A LOT OF
TROUBLESOME MALE STUDENTS.
>> YOU BROUGHT UP A GOOD
EXAMPLE WHEN YOU SAID WE DON'T
BROADCAST TERRORIST DEMANDS.
WE WERE TALKING ABOUT THE
MEDIA.
EXACTLY.
WE DON'T READ THE RANSOM
NOTES.
IT GLORIFIES THE TERRORISTS OR
THE CRIMINALS, HOSTAGE TAKERS,
WHATEVER.
I THINK IT WAS BILL WHO SAID
THE RAPE CASES, THEY DON'T
MENTION THE NAME OF THE
VICTIM.
THE MEDIA IS CONSTANTLY
SELF-CENSORING THEMSELVES.
BUT FOR SOME REASON THEY THINK
IN TERMS OF IN THESE CASES OF
VIOLENT SHOOTINGS THEY CAN'T
SENSOR THEMSELVES.
BILL'S EXAMPLE OF THE RAPE
VICTIM MY EXAMPLE WHEN A MINOR
KILLS THEIR MOTHER, A
13-YEAR-OLD, THEY DON'T PUT
HIS NAME ON THE NEWS.
JIM NORTON GAVE ME A GOOD
EXAMPLE.
IT WAS A PERFECT EXAMPLE WHEN
A FAN RUNS OUT ON TO THE
FIELD, THESE SPORTS COVERAGE,
THEY DON'T FOLLOW HIM ON THE
FIELD.
>> I WAS FEELING LEFT OUT.
>> IT SEEMS FRIVOLOUS, BUT IT
IS A PERFECT EXAMPLE.
MEDIA SENSORS THEMSELVES AND
WHY NOT, ANDY, IN A CASE LIKE
THIS.
>> I AM STILL NOT SURE WHAT
EXACTLY YOU WANT.
DO YOU WANT NO COVERAGE OF
THIS EVENT?
WE COVER TERRORIST EVENTS -- --.
>> LOOK AT WHAT WE HAVE SEEN
SINCE FRIDAY.
IT HAS BEEN WALL TO WALL
COVERAGE.
HOUR AFTER HOUR AFTER HOUR.
I THINK IT IS THAT EXCESSIVE
COVERAGE THAT COULD HAVE AN
AFFECT ON OTHER EMOTIONALLY
DISTURBED PEOPLE TO SAY TO
THEM, YOU CAN GET FOUR DAYS OF
BEING THE CENTER OF ATTENTION
OF THE ENTIRE UNITED STATES.
THAT'S BAD.
>> LET ME TELL YOU THIS.
IF YOU STOP COVERAGE IN THE
FIRST FOUR DAYS, THEN YOU ARE
GOING TO GET YELLED AT FROM
PEOPLE SAYING WHY ARE YOU
COVERING X WHILE THIS IS GOING
ON.
>> I THINK IF THERE WAS A
PRINCIPAL THROUGHOUT THE MEDIA
THAT PEOPLE UNDERSTOOD -- WE
UNDERSTAND WHEN WE HEAR THERE
WAS RAPE VICTIM AND WE DON'T
ANNOUNCE HER NAME WE ARE ALL
FAMILIAR WITH THE PRACTICE.
I STILL REMEMBER THIS GUY'S
NAME.
WHY DO I REMEMBER DILLON
KLEEBOLD'S NAME?
I REMEMBER THAT AS BEING
PARTICULARLY EXCESSIVE.
WE MAY BE APPROACHING IT IN
THIS CASE IN MY OPINION.
JAY TOM, --
>> TOM, HOW DOUDA FINE THE
MEDIA?
IS THE MEDIA FOX NEWS?
IS THE MEDIA NOT TWITTER OR
THE INTERNET?
YOU ARE STILL GOING TO GET
COVERAGE ALL OVER THE PLACE.
NEWS NETWORKS AND NEWS
ORGANIZATIONS SHOULD NOT COVER
THIS, BUT IT IS STILL GOING TO
BE COVERED.
HIS NAME WILL BE OUT THERE.
IT IS GOING TO BE CIRCULATING
ALL OVER THE PLACE WHETHER WE
COVER IT OR NOT.
I AM OPPOSED TO LOOKING AT
THIS GUY'S FACE AND PROJECTED
ON A BIG SCREEN AND SEEING HIS
NAME.
IT IS INTERESTING YOU
MENTIONED TWITTER.
IF YOU ARE LOOKING AT THE
TWITTER HASH TAG, THE INNED
COULD OF THINGS THAT ARE
TRENDING ON TWITTER I HAVEN'T
SEEN HIS NAME TRENDING ON
TWITTER.
I SEE I REMEMBER NEWTOWN AND
SANDY HOOKS.
IT IS INTERESTING.
MAYBE I CAN ASK ONE OTHER
QUESTION OF JEDEDIAH AND THIS
IS FOR MY OWN PURPOSES.
PEOPLE WERE GIVING ALL SORTS
OF ADVICE ABOUT HOW TO TALK TO
YOUR CHILDREN ABOUT THIS.
I WAS HOPING MY KIDS WEREN'T
TALKING ABOUT THIS IN SCHOOL.
I DIDN'T BRING IT UP WITH THEM
OVER THE WEEKEND.
I DON'T KNOW IF SITTING DOWN
AND TALKING TO LITTLE KIDS
ABOUT THIS -- I JUST TURNED
THE NEWS OFF.
DO YOU THINK THEY SHOULD BE
TALKING ABOUT IT IN A FIRST OR
SECOND GRADE CLASSROOM?
>> I DON'T KNOW ABOUT A FIRST
OR SECOND GRADE CLASSROOM, BUT
THE PROBLEM IS KIDS WILL ASK
QUESTIONS.
TV'S ARE ON AND KIDS ARE
COMING HOME FROM POOL AND AND
DOING THEIR HOMEWORK AT THE
KITCHEN TABLE AND MOM AND DAD
ARE WATCHING THIS.
THEY ARE GOING TO ASK
QUESTIONS.
YOU HAVE TO BE PREPARED TO
DEAL WITH IT.
IF KIDS ARE FRIGHTENED --
SOMETIMES KIDS ARE MORE
FRIGHTENED WHEN YOU DON'T GIVE
THEM REAL ANSWERS.
THEY ARE VARY ACCEPT TIFF TO
THAT.
THEY ARE RECEPTIVE TO TRUTH.
YOU HAVE TO ADDRESS IT IF YOUR
KIDS HAVE QUESTIONS.
I WOULDN'T GO OUT OF MY WAY TO
BRING IT UP IF YOUR KIDS HAVE
BEEN UNTOUCHED BY THIS.
BUT IF THEY DO HAVE QUESTIONS
YOU SHOULD BE PREPARED TO HAVE
ANSWERS.
>> WE SPENT A LOT OF TIME
TALKING ABOUT THE SHOOTING.
I GUESS WE CAN JUST GO TO THE
LAST STORY.
I JUST LOOKED UP THE -- THIS
IS ON THE ESPN ANALYST.
I LOOKED AT THE -- I NEVER
HEARD OF THE TERM CORN BALL
BROTHER.
DID YOU, ANDY?
HAS ANYONE HEARD OF THE TERM
CORN BALL BROTHER?
>> I HAVE HEARD IT BEFORE THE
STORY, YES.
>> I NEVER DID.
>> YOU ARE NOT OUT ON THE
STREETS LIKE I AM, TOM.
>> I GUESS NOT.
>> ANDY WEARS THE GLOVES WITH
THE TOP OF THE FINGERS
CUTOFF.
>> LISTEN, I USE THE TERM CORN
BALL BROTHER, BUT ONLY TO
REFER TO MY CORN BALL
BROTHER.
>> AT THE BARBER SHOP WE USE
IT IN A DIFFERENT WAY.
>> LET ME READ YOU THE
DEFINITION ON-LINE.
THIS IS THE URBAN DICTIONARY,
AN AFRICAN-AMERICAN MALE WHO
CHOOSES NO THE TO FOLLOW THE
STEREO TYPE INCLUDE BUT NOT
LIMITED TO BEING A LEADER WELL
SPOKEN AND HUMBLE.
HOW POLITICALLY INCORRECT IS
THAT DEFINITION?
>> WHEN I SAW THE STORY MY
FIRST THOUGHT WAS OKAY RG3 IS
A CORN BALL BROTHER, BUT I
GUESS CHRIS BROWN IS A REAL
BROTHER?
IS THAT WHAT PARKER IS TRYING
TO SAY?
>> I GUESS SO.
AMBASSADOR BOLDEN, YOU SAID,
QUOTE, IF YOU PIGEON HOLE
SOMEBODY AS THE BLACK GUY OR
THE WOMAN YOU ARE GOING DOP
THE WRONG -- GOING DOWN THE
WRONG PATH, BUT I AM
COMFORTABLE PIGEON HOLING
JEDEDIAH AS THE WOMAN.
>> THAT'S AN INSULT TO BILL.
>> BACK TO YOU, ANDY.
>> THANKS, TOM.
>>> COMING UP, STRAP ON YOUR
COMPTON HAT BECAUSE YOU MIGHT
GET SMOKED LOC.
THAT'S NOT A STORY.
THAT'S SOMETHING AMBASSADOR
BOLTEN TEXTED ME.
>>> AN URGING THAT EMBRACES
THE FORCE.
SOME GENE YESES -- SOME
GENIUSES BUILDING A DEATH STAR
LIKE THE ONE SEEN IN ""STAR
WARS".
THEY ASK TO START FUNDING BY
2016 HAS HIT THE 25,000
SIGNATURE THRESHOLD REQUIRING
AN OFFICIAL WHITE HOUSE
RESPONSE.
CAN'T WAIT FOR THAT.
WHY DO WE NEED THIS PROJECT
ASAP?
THEY EXPLAIN.
BY LOOKING A THE A WEAPON
SYSTEM SUCH AS A DEATH STAR
THEY CAN SPUR JOB CREATION IN
ENGINEERING, SPACE EXPLORATION
AND MORE AND STRENGTHEN OUR
NATIONAL DEFENSE.
IN OTHER WORDS TO QUOTE "STAR
WARS" WE CAN ALL LIVELONG AND
PROSPER.
LET'S DISCUSS IN THE --
>> LIGHTNING ROUND.
>> AMBASSADOR, IF YOU SAY OR
EVEN HINT THAT YOU DON'T THINK
THIS IS A GREAT IDEA, I WILL
FLAT OUT CALL YOU A LIAR ON
NATIONAL TELEVISION.
>> I DON'T WANT TO REVEAL ANY
CLASSIFIED INFORMATION, BUT WE
HAVE A FLEET OF DEATH STARS.
>> THAT'S ALL I NEEDED TO
NOY.
THAT'S ALL I NEED -- THAT'S
ALL I NEEDED TO KNOW.
>> JFK SAID WE ARE GOING TO
THE MOON AND EIGHT YEARS LATER
WE LANDED ON THE MOON,
ALLEGEDLY.
ISN'T THIS PROOF THAT IF WE
SAID WE ARE BUILDING A DEATH
STAR WE WOULD BUILD A DEATH
STAR.
>> I THINK WE SHOULD DO.
IT I THINK WE SHOULD DO COOL
STUFF.
I WANT SPIDEY WEB SHOOTERS.
IT IS AMAZING THAT PRESIDENT
OBAMA WOULD HAVE TO RESPOND TO
ME.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO CREATE TO
MAKE THIS HAPPEN.
>> I DO THINK THERE WAS A
PETITION -- I THINK IT MAY
HAVE BEEN A LEGALIZING DRUGS
PETITION THAT LEGALIZED DRUGS
AND THEY DECIDED NOT TO
RESPOND.
>> JIM, NO REAL DISADVANTAGES
TO BUILDING A DEATH STAR, ARE
THEY?
>> IT IS IDIOTIC, AND IF WE
WERE WORKING ON MOVIE PROPS, I
WORKED ON THE END OF "BOOGIE
NIGHTS."
MINE BROKE WHEN I SAT ON IT.
>> YOU HAD TO GO THERE.
>> WHY NOT SEND A PETITION TO
THE WHITE HOUSE TO HAVE THE
PRESIDENT APPEAR ON "RED
EYE."
>> THRAZ -- THAT'S A REALLY
GOOD IDEA.
"RED EYE" FANS, GET ON THAT.
AS A "STAR WARS" EXPERT ON THE
PANEL, BILL, I'M SURE YOU KNOW
ENOUGH ABOUT CONSTRUCTING A
DEATH STAR.
HOW MANY JOBS DO WE LOOK AT
CREATING?
>> 32.
BUT THE THING WE HAVE TO DO IS
LEARN FROM OUR PREDECESSORS.
IF WE ARE TO MAKE A DEATH
STAR, WE CANNOT HAVE SOME SORT
OF EXPLOSIVE DEVICE IN A VERY
SMALL AREA WE CAN EASILY LOCK
DOWN THE PROTECTIVE SPHERE,
AND ALL IT TAKES IS TWO WELL
AIMED SHOTS TO EXPLODE THE
WHOLE THING.
THAT CANNOT HAPPEN.
YOU WERE TELLING ME SOMETHING
SIMILAR WHEN I BUMPED INTO YOU
AND YOUR GROUP WHEN YOU WERE
SINGING OVER A TRASHCAN WITH A
FIRE ON IT.
>> CAN WE SAY IF NOTHING ELSE
WE NEED TO BUILD THIS THING
QUICKLY.
WHEN IT OPENS OR LAUNCHES DICK
CHENEY CAN BE THE ONE THAT
SAYS NOW WITNESS THE FIRE
POWER.
THIS HAS TO BE DONE REQUEST I
CANLY, PEOPLE.
>> ONLY IF I COULD INTRODUCE
HIM.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
ABSOLUTELY.
>> THERE ARE A THOUSAND VOICES
THAT CRIED OUT.
>> WE NEED THE DEATH STAR
FILLED.
>> MY FRIEND IS THE BLUE
ELEPHANT AND HE HAS NO WHERE
TO WORK.
>> I KNOW IT IS PURPLE WITH
THREE LONG EARS.
>> TIME TO TAKE A BREAK.
OH WHEN WE RETURN A
PERFORMANCE FROM TONIGHT'S
MUSICAL GUEST.
>>> WE ARE NEARING THE END OF
2012, AND THAT MEANS IT IS
TIME FOR "RED EYE"'S YEAR IN
KITTEN WHERE WE LOOK BACK AT
ALL THAT IS CAT.
AS ALWAYS, PLEASE HOLD YOUR
APPLAUSE UNTIL THE END.
>> NO ONE EVER HOLDS THEIR
ANNOYING.
AMBASSADOR, ANYTHING TO ADD TO
THAT?
>> WHAT COULD YOU POSSIBLY ADD
TO THAT?
JEDEDIAH?
>> THE MOST AMAZING THING I
HAVE EVER SEEN IN MY LIFE.
>> WE WERE ALL WATCHING
JEDEDIAH WATCH THAT.
THAT WAS MORE ENTERTAINING.
>> YOU MISSED SOME CRYING AND
SOME LAUGHING.
>> IT MAKES YOU WANT TO GO UP
TO A CAT AND DO THIS TO ITS
CHIN.
THEY LOVE THAT.
>> IT MAKES YOU WANT TO BE
ONE.
>> IT WILL STOP A CAT IN ITS
TRACKS.
>> ANYBODY ELSE HAVE ANYTHING
TO SAY ABOUT THAT?
>> I WOULD ALSO LIKE TO
SCRATCH ONE UNDER THE CHIN.
CAN I SECOND WHAT JIM SAID?
>> HOW MANY OF THOSE CATS LIVE
WITH YOU?
>> NOT A ONE.
>> REALLY?
>> NO.
I DON'T REALLY HAVE CATS.
>> IT IS ALL PART OF MY TV
PERSONA.
>> ALL OF THE CAT VIDEOS WERE
NOT SUBJECT TO TV.
>> WE GOT A CAT WHEN I WAS
FIVE AND I THOUGHT IT WAS A
GIRL SO I NAMED HIM SUSAN.
BUT THEN I WAS TOLD IT WAS A
BOY.
SO I NAMED HIM JOHN.
A VERY SPECIAL "RED EYE."
THAT'S THE TRUTH.
>> WE SHOULD ADD THAT TO THE
CAT VIDEO.
>> AND THEN WE GOT A BLACK CAT
WHO I THOUGHT WAS A MALE AND I
NAMED THE CAT WILLIAM.
BUT THEN I FOUND OUT IT WAS A
FEMALE SO I NAMED HER
MIDNIGHT.
BUT I LIKED THE LITERAL NAMES
FOR MY ANIMALS.
>> THANKS FOR NAMING HIM
WILLIAM.
WE WILL CLOSE THINGS OUT WITH
A POST GAME WRAP UP.
GO TO FOX NEWS.COM SLASH RED
EYE.
>>> TIME TO GO BACK TO TOM
SHILLOU FOR THE POST GAME WRAP
UP.
>> JIM, NEW YEAR'S EVE, BIG
NIGHT FOR COMICS.
WHERE WILL YOU BE?
>> BUFFALO.
THE 28th THROUGH 31st,
SUNNY BUFFALO.
>> THAT'S GREAT.
I ALWAYS LIKE BEING IN BUFFALO
ON NEW YEAR'S.
I WILL BE IN SYRACUSE.
>> GREAT.
MAYBE WE CAN MEET ON ROUTE 90
AND MAKE OUT.
>> JEDEDIAH, I HEAR YOU HAVE A
NEW COLUMN.
>> I DO.
I HAVE A NEW COLUMN WHERE I
TAKE ON BOBBIE JINDLE OVER
BIRTH CONTROL PILLS.
>> I WAS SURPRISED TO HEAR
YOUR TAKE.
>> DON'T GIVE IT AWAY.
>> I READ IT THROUGH YOUR
TWITTER FEED.
EVERYONE SHOULD FOLLOW YOU ON
TWITTER.
>> AT JEDEDIAH BILA.
>> AMBASSADOR, WHAT DO YOU
THINK OF THE NEWS OF JOHN
CARRIE.
>> HE IS EXCITED