LATEST ON THE SCHOOL SHOOTINGS
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> WE ARE BACK WITH A SPECIAL
LIVE EDITION OF HUCKABEE.
WE'LL SHOW YOU GRACE MCDONALD.
GRACEY'S FAMILY ISSUED A
STATEMENT.
WE ARE OVERWHELMED WITH THE
OUTLETPOWERING AND LOVE AND
SUPPORT FOR SO MANY PEOPLE.
OUR GRACE WAS THE LOVE AND
LIGHT OF OUR FAMILY.
WORDS CANNOT ADEQUATELY
EXPRESS OUR SENSE OF LOSS.
DARRYL SCOTT'S DAUGHTER RACHEL
WAS ONE OF THE 13 VICTIMS OF
THE BINE BOIN VICTIMS IN APRIL
20TH, 1999.
>> DARRYL, I APPRECIATE YOU
BEING HERE.
IT CAUSES YOU TO RELIVE
PAINFUL MOMENTS 13 YEARS AGO.
I WANT TO BEGIN BYING WHAT
THAT MOMENT WAS LIKE WHEN YOU
REALIZED THAT RACHEL, YOUR
DAUGHTER WAS ONE OF THE
VICTIMS IN THE COLUMBINE
SHOOTING?
I THINK THE FIRST THING THAT
HAPPENS, YOU EXPERIENCE SUCH A
SHOCK AND THERE IS IT A
CERTAIN AMOUNT OF DISBELIEF.
I KEPT EXPECTING HER TO WALK
THROUGH THE DOOR AND EXPECTING
TO SEE HER AND IT TOOK A WHILE
FOR IT TO HIT DEAD CENTER THAT
SHE WAS GONE.
THAT HAPPENS A LOT WITH
PARENTS WHO DON'T EXPECT TO
LOSE YOUR CHILD.
YOU NEVER EXPECT IT TO HAPPEN.
IT WAS A NIGHTMARE.
NYOU KNOW, THE TOUGHEST THING
TO WHAT TO SAY TO THE PARENTS.
IF YOU BE IN THEIR HOMES
TONIGHT AND SIT ACROSS FROM
THEM AND WHAT WOULD YOU SAY
THAT COMES FRO
PEOPLE IN THE COUNTRY WHO CAN
SAY I DO KNOW HOW YOU FEEL IN
>> THEY DON'T NEED ME.
THEY NEED THEIR FRIEND FAMILY.
BUT IF I WAS IN THE SWADINGS,
I WOULD PUT MY ARM ATHEM AND
CRY WITH THEM.
THERE IS IT NOTHING YOU CAN
SAY IN THAT MOMENT.
I WOULD NOT HAVE WANTED A
STRANGER TRYING TO TELL ME
SOMETHING OR GIVE ME INPUT.
YOU JUST HAVE TO GRIEVE.
BEST TING TO DO IS GRIEVE WITH
THEM ASK LOVE THEM.
IT IS SIMPLE ADVICE BUT THE
BEST.
NRACHEL WASED DO YOU BELIEVE
IN GOD.
SHE SAID YES.
SHE COULD HAVE SAID NO .
AND THEN SHE WAS KILLED.
HAVE THERE BEEN TIMES WHEN YOU
HAVE BEEN MAD AT GOL AND BLAME
HIM?
>> NO, ACTUALLY .
YOU DONE GET PREPARED IN A
CRISIS.
THE PREP ADINGS HAS TO BE
THERE BEFORE YOU GO IN A
CRISIS AND OUR FAMILY IS IT A
FAMILY OF FAITH.
AND I FELT EVEN BEFORE RACHEL
DIED, I FELT SOMETHING TO
HAPPEN.
I FOAL LIKE THERE IS SOMETHING
STIRRING IN ME AND WE ARE
BEING PREPARED FOR.
AND WHEN THE TRAMMING TRAG
HAPPENED.
RAY METROPOLITANOR IN PLILIFE
HAD TOLD ME MANY, MANY YIRES
AGO.
IF YOU CAN BE A SEE THROUGHER.
AND NOT A LOOK ATER HAD YOU
WILL HAVE PURPOSE MEETING.
NYOU WILLEE THE HAND MUCH
GOOD.
>> YOU HAVE DONE THAT.
YOU TARTED A INSURANCE TO TRY
TO REACH KIDS IN TALK TO THIM.
YOU TALK TO 18 STUDENTS IN
AMERICA.
THAT YOU HAVOIN AGAIN BECAUSE.
GRIEVE YOU EXPERIENCED.
NIT IS MISUNDERSTANDING AND
THE BILL OF RIGHTS BY A LOT OF
PEOPLE IN OUR NATION .
WE EVER NOT A RELIGIOUS.
WE ARE A NONPROFIT RELIGIOUS
ORGANIZATION.
WE HAVE PRESENTERS AND EACH
YEAR WE REACH THREE MILLION.
AND WE DID ASEMBEE TRAPING.
THE AND WHY TALK ABOUT MATTER.
IN LOIT AND WE TALK ABOUT BE A
SEE THROUGHERS AND LOOLLY.
ERB IS MORE IMPORTANT THRAN
THE WE TALK ABOUT THE
PRINCIPLES.
BUT RACHEL 'STORY CHANGES
THEIRS.
WE HAVE HAD 500 RIRENED IN THE
YEARS.
AND THEY ARE TELLS US IF IT
CHOSEN WILBURN WILBERKS ER.
>> HE FELT LIKE HE WAS LED TO
RHETOR MANNERS ENGLAPPED AND
HE MUCHED TO -- HE RESTORED
MANORS TO CHILDREN.
AND SLAVERY WASAL POLISH .
AND THAT SAME AFTER HIS DEATH.
WONDERFULED THE GROUND.
TOOT TO MANY WANT TO WATER.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH YOUR AND
RACHEL'S REMARKABLE STORY.
THANKS FOR BEING HERE.
UP NEXT.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT THE MENTAL
HEALTH OF THE SHOOTER.
STAY WITH US.
.
'S LOT OF QUESTIONS REMAIN
ABOUT THE MENTAL HEALTH OF THE
SHOW.
DR. JULY WE ALWAYS HEAR AFTER
ONE OF THESE EVENTS THAT THERE
WERE SIGNS THAT THE PERSON WAS
GETTING OFF AND SIGNALS THAT
WE SHOULD HAVE BEEN ABLE TO
SEE .
WHAT ARE THOSE SIGNALS AND
SIGNS THAT WE OUGHT TO WATCH
FOR IN PEOPLE?
>> THE BEST PREDICTOR OF
VIOLENT BEHAVIOR IS THE
SYMPTOMS THAT A PERSON
DISPLAYED IN THE PAST.
AND IN A PROBLEM WITH
SITUATIONS LIKE THIS.
THEY ARE DIFFICULT TO PEG AND
YOU SEE PEOPLE GET WITH DRAWN.
IF YOU SEE A PERSON THAT YOU
KNOW AND LOVE AND CHANGING IN
THEIR BEHAVIOR.
AND GETTING WITH DRAWN AND
PERHAPS THEY ARE HAVING
EXTENDED PERIODS OF MOOD
DIFFICULTIES.
AND WHAT I OFTEN SEE IN FAMILY
MEMBERS AND FRIENDS OF THESE
PEOPLE, THEY WILL IGNORE THESE
THINGS OR GO BOO DENIAL ABOUT
THEM.
TYPICALLY WHEN PEOPLE ARE NOT
ACTING THE NORMAL WAY THAT
THEY BEHAVE, AND ARE TARTING
TO DISPLAY CERTAIN BEHAVIORS.
OF SUBTLE THINGINGS.
START -- WITH STRANGE BELIEFS
AND FIXATED ON THIPPINGS THAT
MAKE -- THINGS THAT MAKE THEM
ANGRY.
GETTING THEM INTO SEE SOMEONE
AND A PROFESSIONAL AND SEE IF
THIS IS IT A PASSING PHASE OR
IS THIS SOMETHING THAT IS A
TIP OF A ICEBERG.
A LOT OF THE ONOUS IS ON FRIND
FAMILY TO GET THEM TREATMENT.
THEY BRING POEM IN MY OFFICE
TO BE EVALUATED AND OTHER
TIMES, PEOPLE ARE IN DENIAL.
IF YOU HAVE A FRIEND OR FAMILY
NUMBER THAT NIDES TO BE
ASSESSED WE NEED TO GET THEM
IN THERE AND ACCEPT THE
DIAGNOSIS.
>> FAMILY MEMBERS ARE FEARFUL
TO TAKE ONE MUCH THEIR
CHILDREN TO SOMEONE LIKE YOU
AND SO AFRAID IT WILL CREATE
MORE PROBLEMS BOY MAKING THE
CHILD THINK THERE IS MANAGE
WRONG WITH HIM.
LET CHANGE. MOOD.
WHEN IS IT A MATTER OF HOW THE
CHILD MISANDING AND YOU HAVE
TO TAKE THAT RICK.
NTHE THAT OF EMPATHY IF A
PERSON IS CAPABLE OF HURTING
CHILDREN AND THINGS THAT
NOMOLLY AS A SOCIETY VALLEY
OUR INNOCENT AND PEL OUT.
WE CAN SEE IF WE TALK THE
ABOUT THE DISREGARD FOR RULES.
AND THE HIGH LEVEL OF
NARCECCIAN.
AND WE REQUESTEDED ISSUES OF
PARTIAL AND WHEN THE PERSON IS
IT NOT RECEIVING SOCIAL
INTERACTION AND PERSONAL
STRESSORS AND WE SHAKE IT UP
IT WILL EXPLODE A COKE CAN.
POEM IMPLODE.
AND MASS SHOOTERS THEY
EXEMPLOYED.
>> THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
NCOMING UP.
MAX LUICATO AND HELPING TO
COPE WITH AN EMOTIONOUS LOSS.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
.
♪
You ever notice that some people
just have a knack
for giving the perfect gift?
They put real thought into it.
And find just...
the right...thing.
How do they do that?
More saving. More doing.
That's the power of The
Home Depot.
Pick up a RIDGID JobMax
multi-tool starter kit and
get a free head attachment.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Sharable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
MY DAUGHTER EMIL I WOULD BE
ONE OF THE FIRST TO GIVE HER
LOVE AND SUPPORT TO ALL OF
THOSES.
BECAUSE THAT IS THE TYPE OF
PERSON SHE IS.
NOT BECAUSE OF ANY PARENTING
THAT MY WIFE AND I COULD HAVE
DONE BUT BECAUSE THOSE WERE
THE GIFTS GIVEN TO HER BY HER
HEAVENLY FATHER.
>> MANY .
FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS AND
MEMBERS OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT ARE UNDOUBTEDLYING
THEMSELVES AND GOD ONE
QUESTION .
HOW DO WE HELP CONSOLE THOSE
GRIEVING FROM SUCH A LOSS.
JOINING ME FROM SAN ANTONIO,
TEXAS.
PASTOR MAX LUCADO .
I APPRECIATE YOU COMING TO
HELP AMERICA FIND HEALING.
27 VICTIMS AND A LOT OF PEOPLE
ARING WHY.
WHY DID GOD NOT ENTERVENE.
HE'S BIG ENOUGH TO DO IT AND
THAT IS IT A FAUR ENOUGH
QUESTION AND I AM SURE YOU
ARED THAT .
HOW DO YOU RESPOND.
>> IT IS IT A FAIR QUESTION
AND A QUESTION WE WREST WILL
WITH IF THERE IS IT A PICTURE
OF UNBRIDALED HORROR THIS IS
WHAT WE NEED TO KNOW .
WHAT HAPPENED FRIDAY, WAS A
PICTURE OF SOMEBODY VIOLATING
THE GREATEST GIFTS THAT GOD
GAVE HUMANITY AND THAT IS FREE
WILL.
99 PERCENT OF THE TIME THEY
USE FREE WILL TO DO GOOD
THINGS AND CHOOSE TO LOVE AND
CHOOSE TO RESPECT.
THEY ARE CONSES AND
OPPORTUNITIES OF FREE WILL.
AND THIS IS IT A CASE AND I
SURE MENTAL ILWAS INVOLVED AND
I KNOW THE DEVIL WAS INVOLVED
AND A CASE WHERE THEY BUSED IT
IS IT AND THIS IS IT WHAT WE
HAVE TO BELIEVE.
GOD DID NOT CREATE THIS, BUT
GOD CAN USE AND TAKE THAT
WHICH WAS INTENDED FOR EVIL
AND TURN IT BOO SOMETHING
GOOD.
LIKE DARRYL ON YOUR BROADCAST
SHOWED US.
THE TERRIBLE DEATH FOR RACHEL
WAS USED FOR GOOD.
GOD REDEEMED SOMETHING.
I DON'T WANT TO SOUND LIKE A
BUMPER STICKER THEOLOGY.
THIS IS WHAT WE HAVE TO COME
BACK TO.
THE GOODNESS OF GOD AND HIS
OPPORTUNITY TO TURN EVIL TO
GOOD.
IS THAT IS IT AN IMPORTANT
POINT.
POEM ARE NOT SAYING IT IS IT A
GOOD THING.
I HEARD PEOPLE TRY TO CREATE
SELF INFLICTED JOY AND SAID
EVERYTHING IS GOD-- GOOD.
ALL THIPPINGINGS WORK TOGETHER
FOR GOOD .
BUT THIS IS IT NOT GOOD.
>> GOVERNOR, THIS STINKS .
THIS IS IT TERRIBLE.
THIS IS IT LIFE AT THE WORST
AND HUMANITY IN THE UGLIEST
AND THE UNDER BELLY OF THE
HUMAN SOUL AND THIS IS BAD.
WE NEED TO HATE IT WE NEED TO
HATE THAT WHICH IS EVIL.
WE NEED TO PRAY AGAINST IT AND
WORK AGAINST IT AND RAGE
AGAINST IT.
WE'LL GET THROUGH THIS.
BECAUSE ULTIMATELY GOD IS
STILL GOOD.
I THINK TWO OR THREE THIPPINGS
WE HAVE TO REMEMBER.
WE NEED TO PRAY OUR PAIN OUT.
IT IS NOT A TIME TO TURN AWAY.
BUT TURN TO GOOD.
FIPED THE COMMUPT TO HELP EACH
OTHER AND ENCOURAGE OTHERS TO
STRAY STRONG.
NTHE GOOD OF WHO AND WHAT GOOD
IS.
HE IS STRONG AND CAPABLE X.
FOCUS ON HEAVEN.
THER IN THE
BASEBALL SUGGEST WOULD THE
ABSEPS OF PAIN.
HIS LIFE WAS UNDERSTANDED ON A
CROSS.
AND GOD TOOK A SLAUGHTER OF
THE 99S AND CRUS FICTION OF
THE SAVOR AND TURNED IT NOTO
ACTS FOR THE SAVIOR.
THERE IS NOTHING GOOD BUT HE
WILL TURN IT IN TO SOMETHING
TO BE REDENTIVE.
NTHEIR KIDS SAW IT ON THE
TELEVISION AND READING AND
TALKING ABOUT.
HOW WOULD YOU RECOMMEPPED THAT
A PARENT SIT DOWN WITH A SON
OR DAUGHTER AND STAY YOU DON'T
HAVE TO BE AFRAID TO GO TO
SCHOOL THIS WILL NOT HAPPEN TO
YOU, MONOPOLIED.
>> THAT IS IT A GREAT
QUESTION, GOVERNOR.
I WOULD SAY THIS IS IT BAD .
THIS IS IT BAD.
WE LIVE IN A WORLD THERE IS
NOT JUST GOOD AND BAD.
BUT THERE IS IT BAD, THIS IS
IT REALLY BAD.
AND HELP OUR CHILDREN
UNDERSTAND THERE IS IT BAD IN
THE WORLD.
THERE IS A DEVIL AND A FORCE
OF EVIL.
AND HE'S NOT GOING TO WIN.
HIS TIME IS LIMITED AND HE'S
ON A SHORT LEASE.
OUR KIDS SEE EVIL EVERY DAY
AND WE NEED TO TELL THEP VILL
IS HERE.
WE ASSURE THEM WITH OUR LOVE
AND FECTION .
AND LET THIM SEE OUR TOURS AND
RECTION AND HONEST HOPE FOR
THEM.
WE DO OUR BEST TO CREATE
WITHIN.
AT A TIME LIKE THIS, THERE IS
NOODS OUT OF HEAVEN, OUTED OF
GOD.
WE HAVE TO TILL OUR KIDS.
WE WERE MILE FOR SOMETHING
DEFENSE.
NYOU GOD WILL BE VICK TOROUS.
MAY I ADD A WORD.
THERE MIGHT BE A YOUNG PERSON
WHO LOOKS TO THE PERSON IN
CONNECTICUT AS A YOUNG PERSON.
I WANT TO SAY TO THE YOUNG
PERSON, THAT IS IT NOT THE
ANSWER.
THAT WILL NOT SOLD YOUR
PROBLEMS.
IF YOU EVER FINDING YOURSELF
LOOKING TO HIM WITH REQUEST
AND NOT DISGUST.
OPEN YOURSELF UP AND TALK TO
SOMEONE.
YOU DON'T WANT TO GO DOWN THE
ROAD.
HE'S NOT THE SOLUTION OR ROLE
MODEL.
MAY GOD HAVE MERCY ON YOU.
DON'T FOLLOW THE FAM EXAMPLE.
>> I CANNOT THRANK YOU ENOUGH
FOR BEING HERE TONIGHT.
I KNOW YOUR SCHEDULE IS
IMCREZIBLY BACK.
THARCHING YOU, LUCADO >> WE
ALL FEEL A SENSE OF GRIEF AND
PAIN.
AND SOMETIMES WE FEEL SO
INCREDIBLY HELPLESS .
AND YET WE CAN PRAY AND IT CAN
MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
>> IF I DIDN'T BELIEVE THAT, I
WOULD GIVE UP IN A FACE OF
SOMETHING AS HORRIBLEEEEEEE
[ Male Announcer ]
WHEN IT COMES TO
THE FINANCIAL OBSTACLES
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAN
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
>> AWEONHT,
>> WAS WAY LEAVE YOU TONIGHT WE
WANT YOU TO SEE THE NAMES AND
AGES OF THOSE WHOSE LIVES WERE
ENDED.
THEIR AGES FROZE FROZEN IN
DEATH.
FROM NEW YORK, GOOD NIGHT.