CONNECTICUT.
NEWTOWN BEE REPORTING ONE
CHILD WAS CARRIED OUT BY A
POLICE OFFICER AND
APPARENTLY THE CHILD WAS
WOUNDED.
HOW WE DO NOT KNOW AND
SERIOUSNESS IS NOT CLEAR
EITHER.
>> IT SAYS DOZENS OF STATE
TROOPERS ARE ON THE SCENE.
THEY'RE ASSISTING LOCAL
POLICE.
HEAVILY-ARMED POLICE
GATHERED AROUND THE SCHOOL
AT 10:45.
THIS IS ALL SO RECENT.
STRETCHERS HAVE BEEN SET UP
AND SAGING AREA SET UP FOR
THE PARENTS OF STUDENTS IN
THE SCHOOL.
VERY TERRIFYING SITUATION IN
NEWTOWN AREA.
OUR COVERAGE WILL CONTINUE.
BILL: COVERAGE CONTINUES ON
"HAPPENING NOW.".
JENNA: IF YOU'RE JUST JOINING
US A SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT.
STILL UNCON FERMED DETAILS.
THIS HAPPENED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL ABOUT HOUR
AND A HALF AGO.
ACCORDING TO WIRES AND LOCAL
REPORTS WE'RE GETTING SOME
INFORMATION THERE ARE
SEVERAL INJURIES AT THIS
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL THIS
FRIDAY MORNING.
A FEW DETAILS ABOUT THIS
AREA.
THIS PLACE, THIS NEWTOWN,
TOWNSHIP, IN CONNECTICUT IS
ABOUT 60 MILES FROM NEW YORK
CITY.
IT'S A TOWN OF LESS THAN
30,000 PEOPLE.
SO SMALL COMMUNITY AND A
SMALL ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AT
THAT WE'RE TRYING TO WORK ON
DETAILS WHAT ACTUALLY
TRANSPIRED THIS MORNING BUT
ACCORDING TO THE LATEST, WE
HAVE UNCONFIRMED REPORT FROM
THE LOCAL PAPER, THE
COURRANT, THERE ARE TWO
SHOOTERS BEING REPORTED.
ONE SHOOTER IS DEAD
ACCORDING TO THIS REPORT.
ANOTHER ONE IS STILL ON THE
LOOSE.
AGAIN VERY SPOTTY REPORTING
AT THIS TIME.
WE'RE WORKING VERY HARD TO
GET SOMEONE ON THE SCENE
THERE.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT A
SATELLITE SHOT OF THIS
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AGAIN A VERY DEVELOPING
SCENE THERE SHORTLY AFTER
9:40 THIS MORNING ACCORDING
TO THE LOCAL NEWSPAPER.
POLICE REPORTED A SHOOTER
WAS IN THE MAIN OFFICE OF
THE SCHOOL.
A PERSON IN ONE ROOM
ACCORDING TO POLICE AND
ACCORDING TO THIS LOCAL
REPORT HAD NUMEROUS GUNSHOT
WOUND.
WORKING TO CONFIRM THIS.
WE HAVE A SOMEONE FROM
SANFORD, CONNECTICUT.
VETO, HOW DO WE FIND ANSWERS
TO THE QUESTIONS?
>> YOU HAVE A LOT GOING ON
HERE, ONE OF THE MAIN
CONCERNS POLICE HAVE YOU
HAVE EVERY SINGLE PARENT
WITH A CHILD IN THIS SCHOOL
TRYING, AND THEY'RE TRYING
TO GET INTO THE SCHOOL AND
YOU HAVE TO KEEP THEM OUT OF
COURSE.
WHAT IS GOING ON, THIS IS
STILL CONFUSING, IT HAS BEEN
SINCE IT BROKE.
NOW YOU'VE GOT A SHOOTER.
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
IS THIS A MALE THAT HAD A
RELATIONSHIP WITH A WOMAN
TEACHER THAT IS IS GOING IN
THERE?
IS THIS SOMEBODY LAID OFF
NOT TOO LONG AGO.
?
YOU HAVE A LOT OF ANSWERS.
THE MAIN THING IS THE
CHILDREN AND YOU MAY BE
STUCK WITH THEM NOW BEING
LOCKED DOWN UNTIL THE POLICE
CAN ACTUALLY GET IN THERE
AND DO THEIR HOMEWORK IN THE
ENTIRE SCHOOL.
THAT'S WHAT YOU GOT GOING
HERE, JENNA.
THIS IS A BEAUTIFUL CITY.
IT IS VERY SMALL.
IT IS RITZY AND QUIET LET'S
SAY.
IT IS VERY DIFFERENT FROM
STAMFORD, BRIDGEPORT, NEW
HAVEN AND OTHER COMMUNITIES
AROUND THERE.
JENNA: QUESTIONS REMAIN AS
YOU MENTIONED AND WE'RE
WORKING TO GET SOME OF THOSE
ANSWERS AS THIS STORY
DEVELOPS.
HERE ARE SOME LIVE SCENE
SHOOTS WE HAVE INTO OUR
NEWSROOM.
VITO, ONE OF THE THINGS
WE'RE WORKING TO GET IS A
PICTURE IN THE LOCAL
NEWSPAPER BEING REPORTED ON
THE ASSOCIATED PRESS.
APPARENTLY THIS LOCAL
NEWSPAPER HAS A PHOTO OF
YOUNGER STUDENTS, SOME
CRYING, SOME LOOKING
FRIGHTENED ACCORDING TO THIS
DESCRIPTION, BEING ESCORTED
BY ADULTS THROUGH A PARKING
LOT IN LINE, HANDS ON EACH
OTHER'S SHOULDERS.
THE NUMBER ONE THING IS TO
TRY TO GET THE KIDS OUT OF
THE SCHOOL.
AT THIS POINT, HOUR AND A
HALF AFTER THIS NEWS BREAKS
IS IT LIKELY ALL THE
STUDENTS ARE OUT?
>> I WOULD, I WOULD DOUBT
THAT RIGHT NOW.
IT TAKES A WHILE.
YOU'RE NOT DEALING WITH HIGH
SCHOOL KIDS, EVEN MIDDLE
SCHOOLKIDS, VERY QUICKLY
THEY CAN GO OUT.
YOU'RE DEALING WITH FIVE TO
10-YEAR-OLDS PROBABLY SCARED
OUT OF THEIR WITS RIGHT NOW.
LITTLE BY LITTLE YOU HAVE TO
TAKE THEM OUT.
MAKE SURE THERE IS NOT
ANYBODY ELSE OR BAD GUY IN
THIS AREA.
LOOKS LIKE IT WILL COME TO A
HEAD PRETTY SOON BUT THE
WHOLE THEN DURING THE COURSE
OF YOUR WORKDAY, WHY, WHAT
HAPPENED HERE?
JENNA: SURE.
>> IS IT SOMEBODY DISGRUNTLED.
DID SOMEBODY BREAK UP WITH
SOMEBODY?
SOMEBODY TREAT THEIR KID
WRONG IN THE SCHOOL?
JENNA: VERY DIFFICULT TO
SPECULATE AT THIS TIME.
VITO, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WE'LL CALL ON YOU AGAIN AS
WE GET INFORMATION.
WE WANT TO SHARE THIS WITH
OUR VIEWERS.
LT. PAUL VANCE OF THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE HAS
THIS TO SHARE WITH US.
HE SAYS THERE WILL BE A NEWS
CONFERENCE ON SITE AT 1:30
EASTERN TIME.
HE IS GIVING TIME FRAME AT
THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
HE SAYS THEY'RE NOT
RELEASING FURTHER DETAILS AT
THIS MOMENT, BUT HE REFERRED
TO IT AS QUOTE, A LARGE
SCENE.
WE'LL GIVE YOU MORE AS WE
GET IT.
>>> RIGHT NOW SOME BRAND NEW
STORIES AND BREAKING NEWS.
JON: YOU KNOW AMBASSADOR
SUSAN RICE WITHDRAWS HER
NAME FROM CONSIDERATION TO
BE SECRETARY OF STATE.
WHY SHE BACKED OUT AND WHO'S
IN THE RUNNING NOW.
>>> ALSO A NIGHTMARE FOR A
FORMER MARINE, JAILED FOR
MONTHS IN MEXICO ON WHAT HIS
FAMILY SAYS ARE TRUMPED UP
CHARGES.
HOW THEY ARE FIGHTING TO
BRING HIM BACK HOME.
>>> ALMOST A CENTURY LATER
NEW INFORMATION ON THE
HINDENBURG DISASTER.
WE'LL LOOK INTO WHAT CAUSED
IT WITH AN EXPERT, ALL
"HAPPENING NOW."
JON: AND A GOOD FRIDAY
MORNING TO YOU.
THE U.N. AMBASSADOR SUSAN
RICE TAKES HERSELF OUT OF
THE RUNNING TO BE SECRETARY
OF STATE, ENDING A LONG
STANDOFF WITH SENATE
REPUBLICAN WHO IS PROMISED
TO FIGHT HER NOMINATION.
I'M JON SCOTT.
JENNA: A BIG DEVELOPMENT
THERE.
HI, EVERYBODY, I'M JENNA
LEE.
AND THE AMBASSADOR MAKING IT
OFFICIAL IN A LETTER TO THE
PRESIDENT SAYING SHE DIDN'T
WANT HER NOMINATION TO
BECOME ANYMORE OF A
DISTRACTION.
AMBASSADOR RICE HAS BEEN
UNDER FIRE AS YOU KNOW WEEKS
AFTER MAKING STATEMENTS
ABOUT THE DEADLY ATTACK ON
OUR CONSULATE IN LIBYA,
ORIGINALLY CALLING THE
ATTACK QUOTE, SPONTANEOUS.
SHE OFFERED DISCLAIMERS IN
THOSE STATEMENTS.
THAT TERM AND WAY SHE
DESCRIBED IT, REALLY UNDER
HEAVY CRITICISM BY HER
CRITICS.
IN THE WEEKS THAT FOLLOWED
THE AMBASSADOR MET WITH
LEADING REPUBLICANS TO TRY
TO SMOOTH OVER THINGS.
NOW HER DECISION COULD HAVE
A RIPPLE EFFECT FROM THE
WHITE HOUSE TO CAPITOL HILL,
PROBABLY RESHAPING THE
MAKEUP OF THE PRESIDENT'S
SECOND TERM CABINET AND ALSO
MAYBE THE SENATE.
WENDELL GOLER IS LIVE AT THE
WHITE HOUSE WITH ALL OF
THIS.
WENDELL, WAS THIS RICE'S
DECISION OR WAS THIS A
DECISION MADE BY THE
WHITE HOUSE?
>> Reporter: JENNA, BY ALL
ACCOUNTS IT WAS RICE'S CALL
ALTHOUGH THERE IS NO
INDICATION PRESIDENT OBAMA
PRESSED HER TO RECONSIDER.
HE ANGRILY CRITICIZED
REPUBLICANS FOR ATTACKING
RICE OVER HER INITIAL
EXPLANATION FOR THE BENGHAZI
CONSULATE ATTACK AND IN A
WRITTEN STATEMENT YESTERDAY
HE SAID, QUOTE, WHILE I
DEEPLY REGRET THE UNFAIR AND
MISLEADING ATTACKS ON SUSAN
RISE IN RECENT WEEKS, HER
DECISION DEMONSTRATES THE
STRENGTH OF HER CHARACTER.
RICE TOLD NBC'S BRIAN
WILLIAMS, SHE DIDN'T WANT TO
BE A DISTRACTION.
>> I DIDN'T WANT TO SEE A
CONFIRMATION PROCESS THAT
WAS VERY PROLONGED, VERY
POLITICIZED, VERY
DISTRACTING, AND VERY
DISRUPTIVE BECAUSE THERE ARE
SO MANY THINGS WE NEED TO
GET DONE AS A COUNTRY.
>> Reporter: MEANWHILE
SOUTH CAROLINA REPUBLICAN
SENATOR LINDSEY GRAHAM SAYS
HE STILL BELIEVES RICE
MISLED THE PUBLIC AND HE
WON'T GIVE UP HIS ATTEMPT TO
FIND OUT WHY, JENNA.
JENNA: THERE WERE MANY
RUMORS SHE WOULD BE
NOMINATED FOR THE SECRETARY
OF STATE POSITION, WENDELL,
IT IS IMPORTANT TO REMIND
OUR VIEWERS SHE NEVER WAS.
>> Reporter: NO.
JENNA: WE'RE STILL WONDERING
WHO WILL BE NOMINATED.
WHAT NAMES ARE YOU HEARING?
>> Reporter: BY ALL ACCOUNTS
JOHN KERRY IS NOW THE
FRONTRUNNER, PROBABLYLY
WITHOUT ANY FIGHT FROM THE
SENATE COLLEAGUES OVER THE
CONFIRMATION HEARING.
KERRY IS THE CHAIRMAN OF THE
FOREIGN RELATIONS COMMITTEE
WITH EXTENSIVE FOREIGN
POLICY EXPERIENCE.
SINCE THE DEMOCRATIC
GOVERNOR OF HIS HOME STATE
OF MASSACHUSETTS WILL CHOOSE
A REPLACEMENT, THE DEMOCRATS
WON'T LOSE A SENATE SEAT AT
LEAST NOT IN THE SHORT-TERM.
WE CAN EXPECT THAT ANNOUNCEMENT
REASONABLY SOON.
WE'RE HEAR FORMER REPUBLICAN
SENATOR CHUCK HAGEL OF
NEBRASKA IS IN LINE TO
REPLACE DEFENSE SECRETARY
HIS WIFE HE CAN RETURN TO
CALIFORNIA.
HAGEL LIKELY TO HAVE EASY
SENATE CONFIRMATION THOUGH
ISRAEL SUPPORTERS SAY HAGEL
IS NOT SUPPORTIVE OF ENOUGH
OF EFFORTS TO ISOLATE IRAN.
A FEW OTHER POSSIBILITIES.
TOM DONILON BECOMES THE
PRESIDENT'S CHIEF OF STAFF.
JACK LEW, FORMER BUDGET
DIRECTOR GOES TO TREASURY TO
REPLACE TIM GEITHNER WHO
SAYS HE WON'T HAVE A SECOND
TERM AND.
JENNA: A BIT OF MUSICAL
CHAIRS AS WE GO INTO THE NEW
YEAR AND SEE WHO FILLS THOSE
POSITIONS.
WENDELL, THANK YOU FOR THE
LATEST.
JON: AMBASSADOR RICE MIGHT
BE BOWING OUT BUT THE
INVESTIGATION INTO OUR
ATTACK ON CONSULATE IN LIBYA
IS FAR FROM OVER.
THE AMBASSADOR DEFENDING HER
RESPONSE IN THE DAYS
IMMEDIATELY AFTER THE
ATTACK.
LISTEN.
>> I DON'T THINK ANYBODY IS
EVER WHOLLY BLAMELESS BUT I
DIDN'T DO ANYTHING WRONG.
I DIDN'T MISLEAD.
I DIDN'T MISREPRESENT.
I DID THE BEST WITH THE
INFORMATION THE UNITED
STATES GOVERNMENT HAD AT THE
TIME.
JON: SOUTH CAROLINA
REPUBLICAN SENATOR LINDSEY
GRAHAM SAID EVEN THOUGH
AMBASSADOR RICE WILL NOT
LEAD THE STATE DEPARTMENT
THE CONGRESSIONAL INQUIRY
WHAT HAPPENED IN BENGHAZI
WILL CONTINUE.
LISTEN.
>> SUSAN RICE, IN MY OPINION
MISLED THE PUBLIC AND THERE
ARE OTHER PROBLEMS WITH HER
TIME AND POLITICS AND THE
NATIONAL FOREIGN AFFAIRS
ARENA.
PROBLEMS WERE DEEPER THAN ME
AND DEEPER THAN BENGHAZI BUT
WE'RE NOT GOING TO LET THIS
GO.
JON: JOINING US NOW FOR HIS
TAKE ON THESE DEVELOPMENTS,
FORMER U.N. AMBASSADOR JOHN
BOLTON.
HE IS ALSO A FOX NEWS
CONTRIBUTOR.
MR. AMBASSADOR, I'M GUESSING
YOU READ THE LETTER TO THE,
THE OP-ED PIECE IN "THE
WASHINGTON POST" THIS
MORNING WHICH SUSAN RICE
TALKS ABOUT WHY SHE DECIDED
TO SUBMIT HER WII DRAWL
LETTER FROM CONSIDERATION.
SHE WRITES THIS AS IT BECAME
CLEAR MY POTENTIAL
NOMINATION WOULD SPARK
ENDURING PARTISAN BATTLE I
CONCLUDED IT WOULD BE WRONG
TO ALLOW THIS DEBATE TO
CONTINUE DISTRACTING FROM
URGENT NATIONAL PRIORITIES.
WERE THERE ANY ENDURING
PARTISAN BATTLES WHEN YOU
WERE SERVING IN THAT SAME
JOB?
>> WELL, PROBABLY SO BUT YOU
KNOW, WHAT'S UNUSUAL ABOUT
THIS CIRCUMSTANCE OBVIOUSLY
IS SHE HAD NOT BEEN
NOMINATED YET AND TO HAVE
THE LITTLE EXCHANGE THAT WE
HAD YESTERDAY, SHE WRITES TO
THE PRESIDENT.
THE PRESIDENT ISSUES A
STATEMENT, RESULTS IN THE
OBAMA ADMINISTRATION
PREEMPTIVELY SURRENDERING ON
A WAR THAT HADN'T BEEN
DECLARED YET.
YOU KNOW WHEN JIM BAKER WAS
CHIEF OF STAFF FOR RONALD
REAGAN, HE OPERATED ON A
PRINCIPLE THAT THE PRESIDENT
NEVER LOSES.
THAT YOU TRY AND STRUCTURE
THINGS SO THAT THE PRESIDENT
DOESN'T TAKE ANY UNNECESSARY
HITS BECAUSE YOU'RE TRYING
TO MAXIMIZE THE PRESIDENT'S
INFLUENCE.
THIS IS AN EXAMPLE OF THE
WHITE HOUSE FOR REASONS
UTTERLY INEXPLICABLE TO ME
ANNOUNCING THEY HAVE LOST
WHEN THEY DIDN'T HAVE TO DO
IT.
THEY COULD HAVE NOMINATED
JOHN KERRY, WHOMEVER, SAID
HE WAS LEADING CONTENDER ALL
ALONG AND AWAY THEY GO.
I THINK IT IS A REAL
INCENTIVE FOR REPUBLICANS ON
THE HILL ON THE FISCAL CLIFF
TALKS OR WHATEVER IT MIGHT
BE, NOT TO OVERESTIMATE THE
PRESIDENT'S POLITICAL POWER.
JON: SHE WROTE ONE OTHER
THING THAT CAUGHT MY EYE.
SHE SAID, AFTER THE
DESPICABLE TERRORIST ATTACKS
THAT TOOK THE LIVES OF FOUR
COLLEAGUES IN BENGHAZI OUR
BOUGHT MUST WORK THROUGH
SERIOUS QUESTIONS AND BRING
THE PERPETRATORS TO JUSTICE.
WE MUST STRENGTHEN SECURITY
AT OUR DIPLOMATIC POSTS AND
IMPROVE INTELLIGENCE IN A
VOLATILE MIDDLE EAST.
IS THAT A BIT LIKE CLOSING
THE BARN DOOR AFTER THE
HORSES ESCAPED?
>> EXACTLY.
THAT IS WHAT SENATOR GRAHAM
AND OTHERS HAVE BEEN SAYING.
THEY WILL CONTINUE TO PRESS
THE INVESTIGATION ON
BENGHAZI.
WHY THE REQUESTS FOR
ENHANCED SECURITY BEFORE THE
ATTACK ON SEPTEMBER THE 11th
NOT GRANTED?
WHY WERE WE UNABLE TO DO
ANYTHING ON THE SEPTEMBER
THE 11th AND WHERE DID THE
ADMINISTRATION COME UP WITH
THE STORY THAT THE TERRORIST
ATTACK WAS SOMEHOW CONNECTED
TO THE MOHAMMED VIDEO?
IN A WAY I THINK SUSAN
RICE'S WITHDRAWAL OF HER
SECRETARY OF STATE CANDIDACY
REALLY CLEARS A WAY
POTENTIAL OBSTACLE.
NOW THERE IS NO TALK ABOUT
RACISM OR SEXISM.
NOW WE CAN GET TO THE POINT
THE PRESIDENT HIMSELF ASKED
FOR, WHAT DID HE DO WRONG?
WHAT DID HIS ADMINISTRATION
DO WRONG THAT LED TO FOUR
AMERICANS BEING MURDERED?
SO I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT TO
PROCEED DOWN THAT ROAD,
PERHAPS STARTING NEXT WEEK
WITH SECRETARY OF STATE
HILLARY CLINTON'S TESTIMONY
UP ON THE HILL.
JON: THAT IS GOING TO BE
FASCINATING TO WATCH.
AMBASSADOR BOLTON, GOOD TO
HAVE YOU ON.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
JENNA: WE'LL GET BACK TO THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE JUST LEARNING MORE
INFORMATION ON WHAT HAPPENED
THIS MORNING.
HARRIS, YOU HAVE MORE FOR US
IN THE NEWSROOM.
>> Reporter: LET'S CATCH
EVERYBODY UP IN CASE THEY'RE
JUST TUNING IN, JENNA.
THIS IS NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL REPORTED A SHOOTING
HOUR AND A HALF AGO.
STATE POLICE IN CONNECTICUT
ARE ASSISTING LOCAL POLICE
HERE IN THE AREA AND HERE IS
WHAT IS BEING REPORTED OF
THE A DISPATCHER WITH THE
NEWTOWN VOLUNTARY AMBULANCE
CORPS SAID ONE TEACHER HAS
BEEN TRANSPORTED TO NEARBY
HOSPITAL IN DANBURY POSSIBLY
WITH A GUNSHOT WOUND.
WE DON'T KNOW THE EXTENT OF
THAT INJURY.
I CAN TELL YOU OTHER SCHOOLS
IN THE AREA ARE LOCKED DOWN.
THIS WOULD AFFECT 5400
CHILDREN IN THIS VERY SMALL
COMMUNITY IN THAT LOCKDOWN
POSITION.
THE SCHOOL WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT, JENNA, HAD TODDLERS
TO FIFTH GRADERS REPORTEDLY.
WHAT WE KNOW NOW IS THEY ARE
ASKING PARENTS TO SIT BY A
PHONE AND WAIT FOR A CALL
FROM THE NEWTOWN CENTRAL
COMMUNITY CENTER.
THEY WANT THAT AS A DISPATCH
RATHER THAN PARENTS SHOWING
UP.
THEY WANT PARENTS TO STAY
BACK SO THEY CAN WORK THE
SCENE, SECURE IT BUT ALSO
TRY TO CATCH SUSPECTS OR ANY
EVIDENCE THAT THEY NEED TO
GATHER AT THAT TIME ALONG
WITH HELPING ANY POTENTIAL
INJURED.
BUT THE OTHER REASON IS THEY
WANT THOSE PARENTS TO BE IN
A LOCATION WHERE THEY CAN BE
EASILY REACHED.
SHOULD THE WORST HAPPEN AND
THEY NEED TO CONTACT THEM
ABOUT THAT.
SO THAT'S THE LATEST NOW.
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
A TOWN ON EDGE, SCHOOLS ON
LOCKDOWN AT THIS POINT.
NO MORE TO REPORT.
NO DETO REPORT ON THE ACTUAL
SHOOTER OR SHOOTERS IN THIS
BECAUSE THOSE REPORTS ARE
STILL UNCONFIRMED.
I DON'T WANT TO FILL IN TOO
MANY DETAILS WE CAN'T FIRM
UP.
OUR FOX AFFILIATE FROM NEW
YORK, NYW IS IN FLIGHT TO
GET THERE BY CHOPPER AS WE
LEARN MORE ABOUT THIS
SITUATION OF COURSE WE'LL
BRING IT TO YOU.
JENNA.
JENNA: HARRIS, A LITTLE MORE
INFORMATION ABOUT THE SCHOOL
WE'RE JUST LEARNING.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
HAS NEARLY 700 STUDENTS.
SO QUITE A LARGE NUMBER OF
STUDENTS INSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
JUST A LITTLE BIT MORE
BACKGROUND.
SCHOOL STARTS ITS DAY AROUND
9:00 IN THE MORNING.
ACCORDING TO THE DISTRICT
EXTERIOR DOORS TO THE SCHOOL
ARE LOCKED AT 9:30 A.M.
ANY VISITORS TO THE SCHOOL
ARE REQUIRED TO RING A
DOORBELL AND STAFF USES
VIDEO TO IDENTIFY THAT
PERSON, JON, AND TO BRING
THEM INTO SCHOOL OR NOT.
SINCE THE SHOOTING HAPPENED
AT 9:30 ACCORDING TO REPORTS,
AGAIN A LOT OF QUESTIONS YET
TO BE ANSWERED IN MANY
REPORTS WE'RE TRYING TO
CONFIRM.
JON: FAIRFIELD COUNTY WHERE
THIS SCHOOL IS LOCATED IS
ONE OF THE WEALTHIEST
COUNTIES REALLY IN THE
ENTIRE COUNTRY.
THIS IS CLOSE ENOUGH TO NEW
YORK CITY, 60 MILES AWAY OR
SO, IT IS CONSIDERED A
BEDROOM COMMUNITY.
THERE ARE CERTAINLY GOING TO
BE A LOT OF PARENTS THERE
WHO COMMUTE INTO NEW YORK
CITY.
A LOT OF THOSE PARENTS ARE
MAYBE JUST NOW FINDING OUT
WHAT HAS DEVELOPED BACK IN
THEIR HOMETOWN, SOME 60
MILES AWAY.
THERE IS GOING TO BE ALL
KIND OF PANIC AMONG PARENTS
TRYING TO GET BACK THERE,
GET TO THEIR CHILDREN.
OF COURSE, AS YOU SAID,
JENNA, THE POLICE ASKED
PARENTS TO STAY AWAY FROM
THE SCHOOL FOR NOW.
THEY HAVE THE SITUATION
UNDER CONTROL AS BEST THEY
CAN THERE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
JENNA: WE SHOULD BE CLEAR.
AS OF RIGHT NOW WE HAVE NO
REPORTS OF INJURED STUDENTS
WE HAVE CONFIRMED.
HARRIS MENTIONED ONE REPORT
OF A TEACHER, POTENTIALLY A
GUNSHOT WOUND TO THE FOOT.
WE'RE STILL WORKING ON
GETTING INFORMATION.
OUR LOCAL AFFILIATE FROM
WSSB IS FOLLOWING THIS.
WE'LL LISTEN TO THE LATEST.
>> WE'RE DOING OUR BEST AS
WE'RE GETTING REPORTS.
STATE POLICE ARE HE IS HAD
TANT TO SAY ANYTHING UNTIL
THEY CAN CONFIRM IT.
THE TONE THEY'RE GIVING US
THIS UNFORTUNATELY WILL BE A
VERY, VERIER SERIOUS
INCIDENT AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENT TRI.
>> WE HEARD THAT FROM
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE STATE
POLICE SPOKESPERSON.
YOU HEARD HIM FROM OUR
COVERAGE MANY, MANY TIMES.
HE HEADED TO THE SCENE.
HE COULDN'T GIVE US A LOT OF
DETAILS WHILE HE HIMSELF WAS
HEADING THERE HE DID SAY
THIS APPEARED TO BE A VERY
SERIOUS SHOOTING AT THAT
SCHOOL.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
THAT IS A K-4 SCHOOL, ABOUT
THE 600 STUDENTS ON
DICKINSON DRIVE.
TO GIVE YOU AN IDEA WHERE
THAT IS LOCATED, I DON'T
KNOW IF WE GET PINPOINT NEWS
TRACKER UP.
WE'RE IN WESTERN
CONNECTICUT.
JUST BELOW THE BOTTOM OF OUR
SCREEN WOULD BE I-84.
IF YOU TRAVEL THROUGH I-84
THROUGH CONNECTICUT JUST
BEFORE DANBURY BEFORE EXITS
10 AND 11, JUST APPROACHING
THE NEW YORK STATE LINE BUT
NOT QUITE THERE.
THIS IS IN NEWTOWN.
A VERY BUSY AREA.
MANY OF THOSE ROADS ACCESS
ON TO AND OFF THE HIGHWAY.
THIS IS AN AREA RIGHT NOW
COMPLETELY LOCKED DOWN.
WE HAVE CREWS ALL OVER THE
STATE COVERING OTHER STORIES
THIS MORNING WHERE STATE
POLICE HAPPENED TO BE AND
THEY REPORTED TO US STATE
TROOPERS FROM ALL OVER THE
STATE OF CONNECTICUT ARE
RACING TO THIS LOCATION.
>> WHAT STRIKES ME REPORTED
THESE ON NATIONAL SCENE WHEN
IT HAPPENED IN OTHER STATES
GENERALLY YOU'RE TALKING
ABOUT A HIGH SCHOOL OR
MIDDLE SCHOOL.
TO HEAR THIS HAPPENING AT A
K-4 SCHOOL IS NOT THAT IT IS
ANYMORE SERIOUS BUT WITH
YOUNG CHILDREN THERE IT IS
THAT MUCH MORE FRIGHTENING.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
THIS IS VIDEO LEN SHOT ON
THE WAY TO THE SCHOOL.
LEN TAKING VIDEO ON HIS
PHONE HEADING THERE.
JUST AHEAD OF HIM, DIFFICULT
TO SEE, DIFFICULTY POINT,
ONE OF THE S.W.A.T. TEAMS,
ARMORED VEHICLES HEADING TO
THE SCHOOL.
THEY RACED TO NEWTOWN FROM
ALL OVER THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT.
CONNECTICUT HAS REGIONAL
SYSTEM WHERE DIFFERENT PARTS
OF THE STATE ARE COVERED BY
DIFFERENT EMERGENCY RESPONSE
TEAMS AS THEY CALL THEM.
THEY WOULD HAVE A WESTERN
DISTRICT EMERGENCY RESPONSE
TEAM WOULD BE IN THAT AREA,
WOULD BE ABLE TO GET THERE
QUICKLY.
AS YOU SEE FROM LEN'S VIDEO
HEADING ON I-84 FROM
HARTFORD, THEY CALLED FOR
S.W.A.T. TEAMS FROM ALL OVER
THE STATE.
MANY, MANY STATE POLICE
RESOURCES THERE.
ONE PERSON WAS TRANSPORTED
TO THE HOSPITAL.
NEWTOWN VOLUNTEER EMS
CONFIRMED TO "EYEWITNESS
NEWS" THEY TRANSPORTED
SOMEONE SHOT IN THE FOOT.
THIS IS NOT JUST SHOTS FIRED
IN THE SCHOOL.
WE NOT AT LEAST ONE PERSON
HURT IN THE GUNFIRE.
>> WE'RE SEEING SAD PHOTOS,
KIDS ARE TRAUMATIZED AS
LEAVING THE SCHOOL.
PARENTS ARE ASKED TO STAY BY
THE PHONE.
DO NOT GO TO THE SCHOOL.
THERE ARE LINES OF PIRNTS AT
THE FIREHOUSE WHERE SOME
CHILDREN WERE EVACUATED.
AT THIS POINT WE'RE GETTING
UNCONFIRMED REPORTS THERE IS
ONE SHOOTER.
SOME REPORTS ARE SAYING TWO
SHOOTERS.
MOST OF THE REPORTS ARE
CONSISTENT THERE ARE SEVERAL
INJURIES.
THERE IS SOME NEW
INFORMATION COMING OUT
SAYING THAT DANBURY HOSPITAL
HAS ALREADY RECEIVED AT
LEAST THREE PEOPLE.
>> AND ALSO WE KNOW
BRIDGEPORT HOSPITAL, NEW
HAVEN HOSPITAL, BOTH ON
STANDBY.
AS WELL AS THEY ARE, ALL THE
HOSPITALS HAVE TEAMS THEY
ACTIVATE IN THE CASE OF
POSSIBLE SITUATIONS WHERE
MORE THAN ONE PERSON OR MANY
PEOPLE COULD BE INJURED.
THOSE TEAMS HAVE BEEN
ACTIVATED.
BRIDGEPORT HOSPITAL, YALE
NEW HAVEN HOSPITAL AND
DANBURY HOSPITAL AS WELL.
AND THAT HAS OBVIOUSLY
RAISED THE LEVEL OF CONCERN.
THEY DO SAY RIGHT NOW THAT
MUCH OF THE WORK THAT'S
BEING DONE THERE AT THE
SCENE IS TRYING TO ACCOUNT
FOR BOTH WHAT HAPPENED AND
WHO IS WHERE.
YOU TALK ABOUT A SCHOOL,
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, AS YOU
WERE SAYING KARA, WE TALK
ABOUT YOUNG CHILDREN, 600
CHILDREN IN GRADES K-4.
OBVIOUSLY HAVE YOUNG
CHILDREN.
YOU HAVE TO FIGURE OUT WHO'S
WHERE.
ACCOUNT FOR ALL THE
CHILDREN.
WHO WAS AT SCHOOL.
WHO WAS HOME SICK.
THAT PROCESS IS HAPPENING.
STAFF MEMBERS, PARENTS, A
LOT OF WORK ON THE
ADMINISTRATIVE SIDE TO
FIGURE OUT WHO'S WHERE AND
ACCOUNT FOR EVERYBODY.
>> YOU ARE TO IN DAYS OF
SOCIAL MEDIA.
THE PRINCIPAL HAS A TWITTER
ACCOUNT --.
JON: YOU'VE BEEN WATCHING
COVERAGE FROM WFSB OUT OF
HARTFORD, CONNECTICUT THAT
IS OUR FOX AFFILIATE THERE,
TAKING ABOUT THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING AT THE SANDY HOOK
HE WILL TRENT -- ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
60 MILES NORTHEAST OF NEW
YORK CITY.
A BEDROOM COMMUNITY IF YOU
WILL.
A GUNMAN, POSSIBLY TWO
GUNMEN HAVE WREAKED HAVOC AT
THAT SCHOOL THIS MORNING.
WE'RE GETTING TWO SEPARATE
REPORTS SAYING THAT THE
GUNMAN IS DEAD BUT MORE THAN
THAT WE DO NOT KNOW.
OTHER INJURIES WE DO NOT
KNOW ABOUT OTHER THAN THE
REPORT OF THE PERSON SHOT IN
THE FOOT AS YOU JUST HEARD.
SO WE ARE CONTINUING TO STAY
ON TOP OF THIS VERY FLUID
SITUATION.
WE'LL BE BACK WITH MORE
INFORMATION AS WE GET IT
STRAIGHT AHEAD "HAPPENING
NOW."
I HAD ENOUGH OF FEELING
EMBARRASSED ABOUT MY SKIN.
[ Designer ]
ENOUGH OF JUST COVERING UP
MY MODERATE TO SEVERE
PLAQUE PSORIASIS.
I DECIDED ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
♪
[ Spa Lady ]
I STARTED ENBREL.
IT'S CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO PROVIDE CLEARER SKIN.
[ RV Guy ] ENBREL MAY NOT WORK
FOR EVERYONE --
AND MAY NOT CLEAR YOU
COMPLETELY,
BUT FOR MANY, IT GETS SKIN
CLEARER FAST, WITHIN 2 MONTHS,
AND KEEPS IT CLEARER
UP TO 9 MONTHS.
[ Male Announcer ]
BECAUSE ENBREL®, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL,
EVENTS INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS, LYMPHOMA,
OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING ENBREL,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START ENBREL IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON ENBREL, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING,
OR PALENESS.
IF YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH, ASK
YOUR DERMATOLOGIST ABOUT ENBREL.
JENNA: WELCOME BACK.
WE CONTINUE TO FOLLOW THESE
BREAKING DEVELOPMENTS OUT OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WHERE
A SCHOOL SHOOTING TOOK PLACE
ABOUT TWO HOURS AGO.
THIS IS OUR AFFILIATE WNYW.
WE'RE GETTING OUR FIRST LIVE
LOOK OVER THE SCREEN.
YOU SEE THE DOG AT THE
CENTER OF THE SCREEN?
ACCORDING TO LOCAL REPORTS
THERE ARE DOGS CURRENTLY IN
THE SCHOOL SEARCHING,
CONTINUING TO SEARCH
PROBABLY FOR EVIDENCE OR
WHETHER OR NOT THERE IS
ADDITIONAL GUNMAN.
WE HEARD NUMEROUS REPORTS ON
THIS BREAKING NEWS THERE WAS
ONE GUNMAN, MAYBE TWO.
NOW WE HAVE TWO REPORT THAT
IS ONE GUNMAN MAY BE DEAD.
BUT AS YOU CAN UNDERSTAND
THIS IS A FAST-MOVING, VERY
FLUID SITUATION AT THE
SCHOOL.
LET'S NOTICE THAT CAR THAT
THEY HAVE CORDONED OFF, JON.
WHAT WE ALSO LEARNED TODAY
IS THAT AROUND 9:30 IS WHEN
THE SCHOOL LOCKS ITS DOORS.
WE ALSO UNDERSTAND AROUND
9:30 IS WHEN THE SHOOTING
TOOK PLACE.
SO STILL A LOT OF QUESTIONS
YET TO BE ANSWERED WHAT
EXACTLY TRANSPIRED HERE.
JON: WE SAW IN THE AERIAL
SHOT JUST A LITTLE BIT
EARLIER, DURING THE
COMMERCIAL BREAK, THE TRIAGE
AREA WHERE THEY SET UP RED
AND YELLOW TARPS, VICTIMS
ARE BROUGHT OUT OF A SCENE
LIKE THIS AND PLACED ON
THOSE TARPS BASED ON THE
INITIAL ASSESSMENTS OF THEIR
PHYSICAL CONDITIONS.
RED OBVIOUSLY BEING THE
WORST.
AND NOBODY WAS ON EITHER ONE
OF THE TARS.
THAT IS POTENTIALLY A BIT OF
VISUAL GOOD NEWS BUT AGAIN
IT'S TOO EARLY TO TELL.
THERE ARE THE TARPS THERE.
THEY ARE AS FAR AS WE CAN
TELL UNOCCUPIED.
THAT IS A BIT OF GOOD NEWS.
THESE DEVELOPMENTS ARE STILL
VERY SKETCHY.
POLICE OBVIOUSLY HAVE THEIR
HANDFUL JUST CONDUCTING THE
INVESTIGATION.
AGAIN AS JENNA SAID THE
REPORT IS THAT THE GUNMAN IS
DEAD.
THAT HAS COME FROM TWO
SEPARATE SOURCES AND THE
EARLY REPORTS OF TWO GUNMEN
HAVE NOT BEEN VERIFIED
ALTHOUGH IT'S LOOKING LESS
AND LESS LIKE THAT MAY BE A
REALITY.
JENNA: SUCH A GOOD POINT.
THE SUPERINTENDENT'S OFFICE
OF THE DISTRICT, THE
SECRETARY THERE WOULD NOT
EVEN CONFIRM THE SHOOTING
ABOUT 45 MINUTES AGO.
SO STILL TRYING TO PIECE
TOGETHER SO MUCH
INFORMATION.
AS WE SHOW YOU THE STUDENTS,
WE WANT TO POINT OUT TO YOU,
THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL OF
NEARLY 900 STUDENTS HAS K-4.
SO YOU'RE DEALING WITH VERY
YOUNG CHILDREN THAT ARE AT
THAT SCHOOL.
WE LISTENED TO LOCAL NEWS
REPORTS THAT SAID ACCORDING
TO THE LOCAL HOSPITALS THERE
HAVE BEEN NUMEROUS INJURIES
BUT AGAIN WE HAVEN'T BEEN
ABLE TO SUBSTANTIATE THAT.
RIGHT NOW STILL TRYING TO
WORK OUT MOTIVE AND WHAT
ACTUALLY HAPPENED HERE AND
WHAT ACTUALLY THE STUDENTS
SAW BECAUSE AS WE ALL KNOW,
AS WE CONTINUE TO REFLECT ON
THESE SCHOOL SHOOTINGS, WHAT
THEY WITNESSED IS SOMETHING
THAT EVERY PARENT OR ANYONE
THAT, YOU KNOW, DON'T
NECESSARILY HAVE TO BE A
PARENT TO CARE ABOUT WHAT
THESE KIDS ACTUALLY WENT
THROUGH.
HARRIS IS WORKING AT THE
BREAKING NEWS DESK FOR ANY
NEW DETAILS ON THE STORY.
HARRIS, WHAT HAVE YOU
LEARNED?
>> Reporter: I JUST GOT OFF
THE PHONE WITH THE POLICE
DEPARTMENT, JENNA, AND THEY
DID NOT INDICATE IN ANY WAY
SHAPE OR FORM THEY ARE
SEARCHING FOR ANYONE AT THIS
POINT.
THEY WOULD NOT CONFIRM MUCH
FOR ME ON THE PHONE.
I CAN TELL YOU THIS.
ABOUT 15 MINUTES FROM NOW
THERE WILL BE A COMMAND POST
SET UP IN THE CENTER THERE,
RIGHT NEXT TO, THIS IS WHAT
I LEARNED, RIGHT NEXT TO THE
TRIAGE PORTION.
JON, YOU POINTED OUT NO ONE
IS ON THAT TARP RIGHT NOW.
THEY HAVE TRANSPORTED ONE
PERSON.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT THEY'RE
DOING ON THE INSIDE TO BRING
PEOPLE OUT.
SO THAT MIGHT BE GOOD NEWS,
IT MIGHT NOT BE, THAT THERE
IS NO ONE OUT THERE ON THAT
TRIAGE RIGHT NOW.
JUST ADJACENT TO THAT WILL
BE A COMMAND POST IN A SHORT
LITTLE WHILE, SO PEOPLE CAN
BE TOLD, A, WHAT NUMBER YOU
CAN CALL IF YOU'RE A PARENT.
THEY HAVEN'T SET THAT UP BUT
THEY'RE WORKING ON IT.
THE FLIPSIDE IS THE NEWTOWN
EMERGENCY COMMUNICATIONS
CENTER THEY WANT PARENTS TO
SIT BY THEIR PHONES AT HOME.
I TOLD YOU THAT EARLIER.
WE WERE ABLE TO CONFIRM
THAT.
AT THIS POINT, AGAIN, NO
CONFIRMATION THAT THEY'RE
SEARCHING FOR ANYONE.
AND HAVING SEEN SCENES LIKE
THIS BEFORE, JON AND JENNA,
THERE IS NOT THAT URGENCY ON
FOOT FROM THIS LIVE PICTURE.
AND THAT'S IMPORTANT TO NOTE
BECAUSE GENERALLY SPEAKING
WHEN THERE IS ACTIVE SEARCH
YOU SEE THAT URGENCY.
IT COULD INDICATE ALONG WITH
THE FACT THAT NO ONE SAID
ANYTHING TO ME THEY WERE
SEARCHING FOR ANYONE, THAT
THEY FEEL LIKE THIS SCENE IS
CONTAINED.
THEIR MAIN GOAL RIGHT NOW IS
THE CHILDREN, SECURING
SAFETY THERE AND ALSO
GETTING AS MUCH INFORMATION
OUT.
I ASSUME WE WILL LEARN MUCH
MORE IN JUST A SHORT LITTLE
WHILE AS THEY GET THAT
COMMAND POST SET UP BUT I'VE
GOT GOOD LINES OF
COMMUNICATION INTO THE TOWN
RIGHT NOW.
WE'LL UPDATE YOU AS I LEARN
MORE.
JENNA: THE ASSOCIATED PRESS,
HARRIS, NOW COMING OUT
SAYING ACCORDING TO AN
OFFICIAL THE GUNMAN HAS BEEN
KILLED IN THE SHOOTING AT
THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
I WANT TO RECAP THE TIMELINE
AND CATCH EVERYBODY UP TO
WHAT HAPPENED OVER THE LAST
TWO HOURS.
WE MENTIONED TO YOU, 9:30 IN
THE MORNING AT THIS
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL THE
EXTERIOR DOORS ARE LOCKED
AND NO ONE IS ALLOWED IN
UNLESS IDENTIFIED THROUGH
VIDEO SURVEILLANCE SERVICE.
AT 9:40, 10 MINUTES AFTER
THAT HAPPENED, POLICE
REPORTED A SHOOTER WAS IN
THE MAIN OFFICE OF THE
SCHOOL.
ONE PERSON IN ONE ROOM HAD
NUMEROUS GUNSHOT WOUND AGAIN
ACCORDING TO POLICE.
WE SAW ABOUT AN HOUR AFTER
THAT STUDENTS WERE BEING LED
OUT OF THE SCHOOL BY THEIR
TEACHERS BUT WE ALSO LEARNED
AROUND THAT TIME, AROUND
10:30 SOME STUDENTS WERE
ALSO STILL IN THE SCHOOL AT
THAT TIME.
JON: WE ARE BEING TOLD AS
JENNA JUST MENTIONED, THIS
OFFICIAL IS IDENTIFYING THE
DEAD AS A GUNMAN, MALE.
WE ALSO KNOW THAT OF THE
SEVEN OR EIGHT TOP PEOPLE IN
THIS SCHOOL THE ONLY MALE IS
THE HEAD CUSTODIAN.
WHAT I'M SAYING IS THAT THE
PRINCIPAL, THE
VICE-PRINCIPAL, ALL OF THE
TOP LEADERSHIP OF THIS
SCHOOL, ARE ALL FEMALES.
SO IF THIS WAS SOME KIND OF
A DOMESTIC DISPUTE THAT
SPILLED OVER INTO THE
WORKPLACE WE DO NOT KNOW BUT
THAT IS CERTAINLY A
POSSIBILITY HERE.
AGAIN, THE GUNMAN WE'RE TOLD
IS DEAD.
ONE PERSON, ONE TEACHER
REPORTEDLY SHOT IN THE FOOT.
AS JENNA MENTIONED ANOTHER
PERSON REPORTEDLY SHOT
MULTIPLE TIMES, BUT AGAIN
THE IDENTIFICATIONS OF THESE
VICTIMS STILL IN THE OFFING.
JENNA: STILL A LOT OF
QUESTIONS ABOUT WHETHER OR
NOT ANY OF THE CHILDREN WERE
WITNESS TO THE SHOOTING AND
WHETHER OR NOT WE HAVE ANY
INJURIES AMONG THE CHILDREN.
RIGHT NOW WE CAN REPORT TO
YOU THAT THE ONLY CONFIRMED
FATALITY THAT WE'VE LEARNED
OF IS THE GUNMAN AS JON HAS
MENTIONED.
WE'RE GOING TO CONTINUE TO
COLLECT INFORMATION, WATCH
THIS LIVE SCENE OUT OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
BE RIGHT BACK WITH MORE
BREAKING DETAILS.
[ clock ticking ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THERE'S A BETTER WAY...
V8 V-FUSION.
VEGETABLE NUTRITION THEY NEED,
FRUIT TASTE THEY LOVE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
OR...TRY KIDS BOXES!
JENNA: BACK TO THAT BREAKING
NEWS OUT OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WHERE WE'RE
WATCHING THE DEVELOPMENTS IN
THIS SCHOOL SHOOTING THAT
TOOK PLACE ABOUT THE TWO
HOURS AGO.
WE'RE GETTING A LIVE SHOT
FROM WNYW.
SEE THE TRIAGE AREA, THE
MULTIPLE MATS ON THE GROUND
THERE?
WE'VE SEEN STRETCHERS OUT.
LUCKILY WE CAN REPORT TO YOU
THAT WE HAVEN'T SEEN ANYBODY
INJURED AT THE SCENE.
ACCORDING TO SOME OTHER
REPORTS, INCLUDING A LOCAL
OFFICIAL, THE GUNMAN THAT IS
AT THE CENTER OF THE
SHOOTING IS DEAD.
WE HAVE MULTIPLE REPORTS
THAT ARE CONFLICTING ABOUT
INJURIES AND WHO HAS BEEN
INJURED.
SO WE'RE GOING TO WAIT UNTIL
WE GET CAN GET MORE
INFORMATION BEFORE BRINGING
THAT TO YOU BUT AGAIN SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, 60
MILES FROM NEW YORK CITY.
SMALL COMMUNITY.
RATHER LARGE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL OF NEARLY 700
STUDENTS, KIN GUARD 10 TO
4th GRADE.
A SHOOTING AT THIS
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
BREAKING DETAILS AS WE COME
INTO THE NEWSROOM.
JON?
JON: NOW THAT U.N.
AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE
OFFICIALLY HAS TAKEN HERSELF
OUT OF THE RUNNING TO BECOME
SECRETARY OF STATE THERE IS
NEW SPECULATION WHO
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S NOMINATION
WILL GO TO.
RIGHT NOW MASSACHUSETTS
SENATOR JOHN KERRY
CONSIDERED TO BE AT THE TOP
OF THE LIST.
LET'S TALK ABOUT IT WITH
PAUL GIGOT, EDITORIAL PAGE
EDITOR OF "THE WALL STREET
JOURNAL." IRONIC, BECAUSE IF
IT HAD BEEN SUSAN RICE, JOHN
KERRY'S COMMITTEE WOULD HAVE
TO CONFIRM HER IN THE
SENATE.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
JON: NOW THAT PROBLEM IS
DONE AWAY WITH.
>> WELL, THAT'S RIGHT.
AND IT WOULD HAVE BEEN A BIG
FIGHT.
JON: NOT A PROBLEM I SHOULD
SAY.
THE CIRCUMSTANCE.
>> IT WOULD HAVE BEEN A BIG
POLITICAL FIGHT.
IN THAT SENSE SUSAN RICE DID
THE PRESIDENT A FAVOR BY
REMOVING HERSELF FROM THE,
FROM THE DISCUSSIONS SO THAT
THEY WON'T HAVE TO HAVE THIS
FIGHT AND THE PRESIDENT
WON'T HAVE TO SPEND THE
POLITICAL CAPITAL HE WOULD
HAVE HAD TO SPEND TO GET HER
CONFIRMED.
JON: INTERESTING, EVEN
REPUBLICANS LIKE SENATOR
McCAIN ARE GENERALLY
PRAISING JOHN KERRY.
IS HE A SLAM DUNK?
>> REMEMBER, THE SENATE'S A
CLUB.
JON: YEAH.
>> LESS SO THAN IT USED TO
BE BUT IT'S STILL A CLUB AND
THE ONLY SENATOR THAT I CAN
RECALL WHO WAS NOT CONFIRMED
WHEN HE WAS NAMED TO A
CABINET POSITION WAS THE
LATE JOHN TOWER WHEN GEORGE
H.W. BUSH APPOINTED HIM TO
BE DEFENSE SECRETARY.
HE WAS DEFEATED.
SO MOST SENATORS GET THE
JOBS WHEN THEY'RE NOMINATED.
I THINK JOHN KERRY WOULD NOT
BE AN EXCEPTION.
JON: WHAT ABOUT THE
CRITICISM THAT, YOU KNOW,
CAME UP DURING HIS
PRESIDENTIAL CAMPAIGN?
THIS WAS A YOUNG MAN WHO
WENT TO SITE IN VIETNAM.
HE CAME HOME AND SPOKE OUT
STRONGLY AGAINST THE VIETNAM
WAR AND ESPECIALLY ABOUT THE
CONDUCT OF AMERICAN SOLDIERS
THERE.
IS THAT GOING TO BEDEVIL
HIM?
>> I THINK IT WILL IN SOME
QUARTERS.
I THINK IT WILL BE RAISED.
I DON'T KNOW WHETHER
SENATORS THEMSELVES OR HOW
MANY OF THEM WILL HAVE THE
REAL STOMACH TO DO THAT
BECAUSE THEY WILL SAY TO
THEMSELVES, WELL, YOU KNOW,
THAT WAS VETTED BEFORE.
HE IS NOT RUNNING FOR
PRESIDENT.
HE IS RUNNING TO BE, TO WORK
FOR ANOTHER PRESIDENT.
I THINK SOME OF THE OTHER
THINGS WILL COME UP THOUGH.
JOHN KERRY'S VIEWS ON SYRIA
WHERE HE SAID WE COULD DEAL
WITH BASHAR ASSAD
PREVIOUSLY.
WANTED TO HAVE ACCOMMODATION
WITH HIM.
NOW WE KNOW THAT IS TOTALLY
WRONG.
YOU WILL SEE SOME OF THOSE
ISSUES VET THE BUT I DON'T
KNOW HOW MUCH THE SENATE
REALLY WANTS TO FIGHT AGAIN
OVER VIETNAM.
JON: WHAT ABOUT FOREIGN
POLICY, LET'S SAY HE GETS
THE JOB AS JOHN KERRY
UNDERSECRETARY OF STATE.
WHAT DO YOU SEE HAPPENING?
>> I DON'T SEE MUCH
DIFFERENCE BETWEEN WHAT
WE'VE SEEN.
THIS ADMINISTRATION RUNS
FOREIGN POLICY MOSTLY OUT OF
THE WHITE HOUSE.
IT HAS FOR FOUR YEARS.
I THINK IT WOULD FOR ANOTHER
FOUR YEARS.
JOHN KERRY WOULD BE ABLE TO
ADVISE AT THE MARGINS, MAYBE
SOMEWHAT LESS HAWKISHLY THAN
HILLARY CLINTON HAS, BELIEVE
IT OR NOT.
HE IS VERY RELUCTANT TO
INTERVENE OVERSEAS, FOR
EXAMPLE.
MILITARILY HE LIKES TO DEFER
TO THE UNITED NATIONS.
IN THAT SENSE NOT MUCH OF A
CHANGE FROM BARACK OBAMA.
>> VERY QUICKLY ON THE
POLITICAL CALCULATION THOUGH,
THE WHITE HOUSE GENERALLY
WOIP THINK ABOUT NOMINATING
A SENATOR IF THEY DIDN'T
FEEL THEY COULD GET ANOTHER
DEMOCRAT TO REPLACE HIM.
WHAT ABOUT SCOTT BROWN
RUNNING TO REPLACE, WELL,
SECRETARY KERRY IF HE IS
CONFIRMED?
>> THAT WOULD BE ONE OF THE
WHITE HOUSE'S CALCULATIONS.
DO THEY WANT TO TAKE THAT
RISK OF AN OPEN SEAT.
IF SCOTT BROWN RAN, HE WOULD
HAVE A VERY GOOD SHOT
WINNING AGAIN.
THAT MIGHT BE PART OF THEIR
CALCULATION.
ON THE OTHER HAND, THEY
STILL HAVE A FIVE-SEAT
MAJORITY.
THEY WOULD STILL HAVE A
FOUR-SEAT MAJORITY EVEN IF
THEY LOST THAT SEAT.
JON: INTERESTING, PAUL.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
JON: YOU CAN CATCH PAUL
TOMORROW AS ALWAYS, 2:00
P.M. EASTERN TIME DURING THE
"JOURNAL EDITORIAL REPORT"
RIGHT HERE ON FOX NEWS
CHANNEL.
JENNA: AND, JON, WE HAVE
BRAND NEW DEVELOPMENTS IN
THE SCHOOL SHOOTING OUT OF
CONNECTICUT.
A LIVE LOOK AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, 60 MILES FROM
NEW YORK CITY.
ACCORDING TO AN UNNAMED
OFFICIAL TALKING TO THE
ASSOCIATED PRESS THE SHOOTER
IS DEAD.
AT LEAST ONE TEACHER
WOUNDED.
AND APPARENTLY THE STUDENTS
WHEN THIS HAPPENED, THE
SHOOTING, WERE SENT OUT INTO
THE PARKING LOT.
WE SHOWED YOU THAT ONE
PICTURE, ONE GROUP OF THE
STUDENTS BEING LED OUT IN A
LINE BUT APPARENTLIES A THE
SCENE IS COMING TOGETHER
WE'RE GETTING THIS PICTURE,
ONE SHOOTER, A TEACHER
WOUNDED AND A LOT OF
QUESTIONS ABOUT UNCONFIRMED
INJURIES THAT WE'VE HEARD
FROM MULTIPLE SOURCES IN AND
AROUND THE AREA.
WANT TO POINT OUT ONE MORE
THING.
ALTHOUGH WE HEAR THE SHOOTER
IS DEAD WE TOLD YOU ABOUT 40
MINUTES AGO WE WERE HEARING
REPORTS THERE MIGHT BE TWO
SHOOTERS.
RIGHT NOW THOSE REPORTS ARE
UNCONFIRMED AND WE'RE HEAR
BEING MORE DETAILS THE
SHOOTER PAVE HAD TWO GUNS.
AS THESE STORIES DEVELOP
OFTEN TIMES WE HAVE TO GO
BACK TO PAINT PIECES OF THE
PICTURE EXACTLY WHAT
HAPPENED HERE.
ACCORDING TO THE ASSOCIATED
PRESS, THE SHOOTER DEAD.
AT LEAST ONE TEACHER
WOUNDED.
THE INJURIES UNKNOWN.
AND AT THAT TIME NO REPORTS
OF INJURIES WHEN IT COMES TO
STUDENTS BUT WE'RE STILL
WORKING ON THAT INFORMATION.
AS WE LEARN MORE WE WILL
BRING THAT TO YOU.
BE RIGHT BACK WITH MORE
"HAPPENING NOW."
[ Male Announcer ]
RED LOBSTER'S
HITTING THE STREETS
TO TELL REAL PEOPLE ABOUT
OUR NEW 15 UNDER $15 MENU.
OH MY GOODNESS!
OH MY GOSH,
THIS LOOKS AMAZING!
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR NEW MAINE STAYS!
15ENTREES UNDER $15,
SEAFOOD, CHICKEN AND MORE!
OOTHE TILAPIAWITH ROASTEDEGETAB!
I'M ACTUALLY LOOKING AT
THE WO GRILLED CHICKEN
WITH PORTOBELLO WINE SAUCE.
AT PORK CHOP
WAS GREAT!
NO MORE
FAST FOOD FRIDAY'S!
WE'RE GOING TO GO
TO RED LOBSTER.
YEP.
[ Male Announcer ]
COME TRY OUR NEW MENU
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
JON: "HAPPENING NOW", STILL
TRYING TO CLARIFY EXACTLY
WHAT HAPPENED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, ABOUT 9:30 THIS
MORNING, A LITTLE OVER TWO
HOURS AGO, WHEN A GUNMAN
APPARENTLY WALKED INTO SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WITH
TWO GUNS WE ARE TOLD AND
OPENED FIRE.
THERE ARE REPORT THAT IS ONE
TEACHER WAS SHOT IN THE
FOOT.
WE'RE TOLD ANOTHER PERSON
WAS SHOT MULTIPLE TIMES, AND
THE GUNMAN IS CONFIRMED TO
BE DEAD.
BUT AGAIN, A VERY CHAOTIC
SCENE.
WE DON'T KNOW WHETHER THERE
WERE ANY STUDENTS INJURED.
WE DON'T KNOW WHETHER
STUDENTS WITNESSED THIS
TERRIBLE EVENT.
OBVIOUSLY THE PARKING LOT IS
FULL OF EMERGENCY RESPONSE
VEHICLES.
PARENTS HAVE BEEN TOLD TO
STAY AWAY.
THERE IS A FIREHOUSE WHERE
PARENTS ARE BEING TOLD TO
GATHER TO FIND OUT ABOUT THE
SITUATION REGARDING THEIR
CHILDREN.
AGAIN, WE HAVE NO INDICATION
AT THIS POINT THAT ANY
CHILDREN WERE ACTUALLY SHOT
OR AFFECTED BY THIS BUT,
AGAIN, THE INFORMATION, IT
IS STILL A VERY CHAOTIC
SCENE, THIS INCIDENT, LESS
THAN, WELL, JUST ABOUT TWO
HOURS OLD NOW.
BECAUSE OF THE CHAOS AND THE
QUESTIONS YET TO BE ANSWERED
F THE
ANSWERS BUT AGAIN THE GUNMAN
IS REPORTED TO BE DEAD.
INITIAL REPORTS HAD TWO
GUNMEN INVOLVED.
THAT OFTEN RESULTS FROM
MULTIPLE PEOPLE SAYING THAT
THEY SAW SLIGHTLY DIFFERENT
THINGS, SLIGHTLY DIFFERENT
DESCRIPTIONS.
SO IN AN ABUNDANCE OF
CAUTION POLICE WILL
SOMETIMES BE ON THE LOOKOUT
FOR MORE THAN ONE GUNMAN BUT
AT THIS POINT WE DON'T HAVE
ANY INDICATION THAT IS THE
CASE.
AGAIN YOU CAN SEE OUR FOX
FILL AT, WNYW CHOPPER IS
OVER THE SCHOOL IN THE AIR.
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, LESS
THAN TWO OURS AGO WE'LL KEEP
YOU UPDATED AS THE SITUATION
CHANGE.
JENNA: A NEW REPORT FROM THE
SENATE INTELLIGENCE
COMMITTEE FIND ENHANCED
INTERROGATION TECHNIQUES
USED ON 9/11 SUSPECTS WERE
IN EFFECTIVE.
THIS IS A 6,000 PAGE REPORT.
IT IS NOT MADE PUBLIC, BUT
ONE OFFICIAL SAYS
WATERBOARDING USED ON KHALID
SHEIKH MOHAMMED DIDN'T HELP
FIND USAMA BIN LADEN AND
WERE ACTUALLY COUNTER
PRODUCTIVE TO THE WAR ON
TERROR.
WE'RE JOINED BY MIKE BAKER,
A FORMER CIA OPERATIVE.
WE'RE MENTIONED THIS REPORT
WAS PASSED ALONG PARTISAN
LINES IN THIS COMMITTEE.
THERE IS CONTROVERSY ABOUT
IT.
YOUR THOUGHTS?
>> IT SHOULDN'T BE ANY
SURPRISE THE CIVIL LIBERTIES
GROUPS AND DEMOCRATS ON THE
COMMITTEE JUMPED ON BOARD
WITH THIS AND REPUBLICANS
DID NOT.
THERE APPEAR TO BE, THIS IS
PART OF THIS IS SPECULATION,
SEEMS IF THEY WENT THROUGH
THE REPORT AND CALLING IT AN
INDEPENDENT REPORT BUT I DO
BELIEVE IT WAS PARTISAN,
THERE WERE SOME THINGS
OMITTED.
THERE WERE A LOT OF
INTERVIEWS THAT WEREN'T DONE
WITH PEOPLE DIRECTLY
INVOLVED BUT, YOU KNOW,
CONTINUES SORT OF THE
DRUMBEAT THAT TOOK PLACE FOR
YEARS DURING THE PREVIOUS
ADMINISTRATION, DURING THE
BUSH ADMINISTRATION BY
DEMOCRATS AND PEOPLE ON
CIVIL LIBERTIES SIDE, THEY
GRAB THE HIGH GROUND.
THEY SAID LOOK, YOU EITHER
TALK AND CHAT TO A DETAINEE,
YOU KNOW, TRY TO WIN THEM
OVER AND GET INFORMATION, OR
IT'S TORTURE.
THEIR POINT WAS AND THEY
GRABBED THIS HIGH GROUND
EARLY ON IN DEBATE, THERE IS
NOTHING IN BETWEEN.
THAT IS INSANE.
THAT IS NONSENSE.
OF COURSE THERE IS ENHANCED
TECHNIQUES IN BETWEEN THAT
FALLWELL SHORT OF TORTURE.
JENNA: CAN YOU GIVE US AN
EXAMPLE.
>> SLEEP DEPRIVATION UNDER
CONTROLLED CIRCUMSTANCES.
TEMPERATURE CONTROL.
AUDIO ISSUES.
STRESSED POSITIONS.
PART OF THIS IS THAT WE
ALREADY RELEASED SO MUCH
INFORMATION ABOUT THAT
PROGRAM.
JENNA: YOU BRING US TO A
LARGER POINT HIRE.
THIS IS JUST ONE REPORT BUT
I WOULD LIKE TO TALK TO YOU
A LITTLE BIT ABOUT THE CIA
HOW IT OPERATES NOW AND HOW
IT DOES ITS JOB WHICH IS
ULTIMATELY TO PROTECH THE
UNITED STATES OF AMERICA.
THERE HAS BEEN SO MUCH
HAPPENED IN THE LAST 10
YEARS BUT THERE'S ALSO A LOT
THAT HAPPENED IN THE LAST
SEVERAL MONTHS, WITH LIBYA,
WITH THE PETRAEUS SCANDAL AS
WELL.
HOW DO YOU THINK THIS PLAYS
INTO THE ACTUAL WORK THAT
THE CIA NEEDS TO ACCOMPLISH
ON A DAILY BASIS?
>> RIGHT.
WE WOULD LIKE TO THINK THE
THREATS TO AMERICA FROM
TERRORISM HAVE ENDED.
THERE WAS A LITTLE BIT OF
THAT GROUND SWELL FOR A
WHILE.
PEOPLE REALIZED, NO, THAT IS
NOT THE CASE.
THERE ARE STILL HOSTILE
ELEMENTS OUT THERE THAT
SPEND THEIR DAYS FIGURING
OUT HOW TO ATTACK US AND OUR
ALLIES.
WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT ENHANCED
TECHNIQUES, WHEN YOU TALK
ABOUT TAKING THAT OFF THE
TABLE, AND THE AGGRESSIVE
INTEAR GRADUATION TECHNIQUES
WERE STOPPED BY BUSH
ADMINISTRATION.
IT HAPPENED YEARS AGO.
IT IS PRETTY CLEAR TO OUR
ENEMIES OVERSEAS WHAT IT IS
WE CAN AND CAN'T DO.
JENNA: HOW DOES THAT AFFECT
OUR ABILITY TO PROTECH THE
COUNTRY?
WHAT HAVE WE REALLY LEARNED,
IF WE TAKE INDEPENDENT OF
THIS REPORT, WHAT HAVE WE
LEARNED?
ARE WE BETTER OFF?
>> WE ARE BETTER OFF BECAUSE
WE UNDERSTAND THE ENEMY
MORE.
WE HAD A LOT OF SUCCESS OVER
THE YEARS TAKING OUT A LOT
OF THEIR KEY PERSONNEL.
THEY HAVE ALMOST SEEMS LIKE
BOTTOMLESS POOL OF POTENTIAL
RECRUITS.
BUT WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT, ARE
WE BETTER OFF?
WELL, IT'S A LITTLE BIT LIKE
THIS REPORT, RIGHT?
HOW LONG IS A PIECE OF
STRING?
PEOPLE SAY TECHNIQUES, I
KEEP WANTING TO GO BACK TO
THE REPORT, THESE TECHNIQUES
DIDN'T WORK.
IT IS INANE TO SAY THEY
DIDN'T WORK EVER.
THE REALITY IS, ALWAYS A
LITTLE BIT MORE COMPLICATED.
THE REALITY IS, SOMETIMES
ENHANCED TECHNIQUES WORK,
SOMETIMES THEY DON'T.
WHAT WE DID THOUGH IN OUR
RUSH TO SHOW HOW RIGHTEOUS
WE ARE DURING THIS PROCESS
WAS WE TOOK THEM COMPLETELY
OFF THE TABLE.
WE REMOVED THE ELEMENT OF
SURPRISE FROM THE KIT BAG.
WHETHER YOU USE THEM OR NOT,
YOU DON'T TELL THE ENEMY
WHAT YOU CAN AND CAN'T DO.
WHAT WE DID --.
JENNA: WHAT IS THE DAMAGE
FOR THAT?
>> THE DAMAGE IS, GOING
FORWARD AND GOING FORWARD
FOR QUITE SOME TIME EVER
SINCE THE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION SAID ALL WE
COULD DO WITH WHAT IS ARMY
FIELD MANUAL, I COULDN'T
BREAK MY TEENAGE DAUGHTER
WITH THE ARMY FIELD MANUAL.
YOU ADVISE THOSE IN THE
FUTURE WHO WORK AGAINST US
IF WE PICK THEM UP OFF THE
BATTLEFIELD THEY THOUGH
EXACTLY WHAT WE CAN AND
CAN'T DO.
THE ELEMENT OF SURPRISE IS
IMPORTANT IN THE
INTERROGATION PROCESS.
JENNA: AS WE LOOK AHEAD TO
THE YEAR AHEAD AND HOW SAFE
WE ARE.
GREAT TO HAVE YOU ON SET
WITH US, MIKE.
>> THANK YOU.
JENNA: REALLY APPRECIATE IT.
JON?
JON: A FOX NEWS ALERT AND WE
ARE GOING TO TAKE YOU BACK
NOW TO A LIVE LOOK ABOVE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECT CULT.
THIS IS NEW VIDEO JUST INTO
THE FOX NEWSROOM FROM OUR
WNYW CHOPPER.
YOU SEE THE CORDONED OFF
AREA IN THE PARKING LOT OF
THAT SCHOOL WHERE NINE: 40
THIS MORNING A GUNMAN WALKED
IN TO THE SCHOOL AND
CARRYING TWO GUNS AND OPENED
FIRE.
ONE PERSON SHOT MULTIPLE
TIMES.
THE A TEACHER SHOT IN THE
FOOT.
THE GUNMAN HIMSELF IS
REPORTED TO BE DEAD.
YOU CAN SEE PEOPLE CARRYING
CHILDREN OUT.
THIS WAS AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
AND IS AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WHAT CHILDREN SAW OR HEARD
WE DO NOT YET KNOW.
PARENTS HAVE BEEN ASKED TO
STAY AWAY.
THE CHILDREN WERE TAKEN OUT
INTO THE PARKING LOT AFTER
THE SHOTS RANG OUT.
BUT A VERY FLUID SITUATION
AND A LOT OF QUESTIONS AS TO
WHAT HAPPENED THERE.
WE'LL BE BACK WITH MORE
COVERAGE IN JUST A MOMENT.
OK!
IT'S A NEW WAY
TO GET CASH BACK DEALS
AND IT'S CALLED BANKAMERIDEALS.
I SIGN IN
TO MY ONLINE BANKING...
CLICK THE "CASH BACK DEALS"
TAB...
AND PICK THE DEALS I WANT.
I JUST USE MY BANK OF AMERICA
DEBIT OR CREDIT CARD WHEN I PAY.
AND THEN I GET
UP TO 15% CASH BACK...
PUT INTO MY ACCOUNT!
I KNOW, RIGHT?
[ Male Announcer ]
INTRODUCINBANKAMERIDEALS,
FREE FOR
ONLINE BANKING CUSTOMERS.
SIGN IN TO YOUR ONLINE BANKING
TO CHOOSE YOUR DEALS TODAY.
JON: FOX NEWS ALERT AND A
VERY FLUID AND CHAOTIC
SITUATION IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WHERE A GUNMAN
WALKED INTO AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL 9:30 EASTERN TIME
THIS MORNING A LITTLE OVER
TWO HOURS AGO AND OPENED
FIRE.
WE'RE TOLD THAT GUNMAN IS
DEAD BUT WHAT ARE THE OTHER
PEOPLE INSIDE THE SCHOOL?
HARRIS HAS SOME NEW
INFORMATION FOR US FROM THE
BREAKING NEWS DESK.
HARRIS?
>> Reporter: I CAN TELL YOU
THAT A CODE RED WAS ISSUED
TO THIS TOWN NOT LONG AGO
AND NOW WE'RE HEARING FROM
SEPARATE --, I WANT TO DRAW
EVERYBODY'S ATTENTION TO
SOMETHING WE'RE SEEING IN
THE MIDDLE OF THE SCREEN.
THE CAR THAT IS PULLING IN
THE CENTER NOW APPEARS TO BE
THAT OF THE TYPE THAT A
CORONER'S OFFICE WOULD USE.
WE'RE WORKING NOW, WE'RE
HEARING IN THE NEWSROOM THAT
FROM DIFFERENT SOURCES THAT
THERE ARE MULTIPLE INJURIES
AND IN THIS NOW, POSSIBLY
CHILDREN AMONG THEM.
I HAVE NOT BEEN ABLE TO GET
THE MAYOR, THE POLICE
OFFICERS, TO CONFIRM THIS
FOR ME BUT I CAN TELL YOU
THAT AT 1:00, AS WE REPORTED,
1:00 P.M. EASTERN HERE, THEY
WILL BE HOLDING A NEWS
CONFERENCE TO LET EVERYBODY
KNOW WHAT THEY HAVE LEARNED
ABOUT THE SITUATION AND
BRING US ALL UP TO SPEED AND
WHO WAS INJURED AND POSSIBLY
WORSE TODAY.
REPORTS, YOU'RE SEEING IT ON
OUR SCREEN RIGHT NOW, OF
MULTIPLE INJURIES,
FATALITIES AS WELL AT THE
SCHOOL.
I'M NOT ABLE TO CONFIRM WITH
SOURCES ON THE GROUND BUT I
HAVE HEARD NOW FROM
DIFFERENT PEOPLE AWAY FROM
THE SCENE, INCLUDING NEARBY
MAYOR OF DANBURY, MARK
BOUTON, WHO SAID MULTIPLE
PEOPLE ARE HURT IN THIS.
AS WE LEARN MORE WE'LL BRING
IT TO YOU.
JON, JENNA.
JENNA: HARRIS, YOU MENTIONED
MAYOR MARK BOWDEN ON THE
PHONE FROM NEIGHBORING
DANBURY.
MR. MAYOR, WHAT CAN YOU TELL
US ABOUT THE SITUATION AND
ABOUT THE POTENTIAL
INJURIES?
>> WELL AT THIS POINT OUR
HOSPITAL IS TREATING v.
VICTIMS IN DANBURY.
THE THERE WILL BE A PRESSER
AT 1:00 THE PRESS WILL BE
ABLE TO ATTEND TO GET MORE
DETAILS WHAT HAPPENED.
OBVIOUSLY OUR HEARTS AND
PRAYERS GO OUT TO THE FOLKS
AND VICTIMS AND FAMILIES OF
THE VICTIMS RIGHT NOW.
IT IS A DIFFICULT TIME FOR
EVERYBODY IN THE GREATER
DANBURY AREA.
ALL OF OUR SCHOOLS AT
DANBURY HAVE HEIGHTENED
POLICE AWARENESS AND
PRESENCE AS WELL AS ALL THE
REGIONAL SCHOOLS IN THE
AREA.
SO WE'RE WORKING ON IT HARD
AND WE'LL BRING ALL THE
ASSISTANCE WE CAN TO
NEWTOWN.
JENNA: MR. MAYOR, YOU
MENTIONED THREE VICTIMS AT
THE HOSPITAL, WHAT CAN YOU
TELL US ABOUT THEM.
ARE THEY TEACHERS OR
STUDENTS?
>> I CAN'T DISCUSS WHO THEY
ARE AND NATURE OF THEIR
INJURIES.
I WILL TELL YOU THAT SOME OF
THE INJURIES ARE, ARE
SERIOUS BUT OTHER THAN THAT
I CAN'T DISCUSS IT.
JENNA: WHAT ABOUT THE
CHILDREN?
DO WE KNOW IF THE CHILDREN
IN THE SCHOOL WITNESSED THIS
INCIDENT?
DO YOU KNOW IF IT HAPPENED
INSIDE A CLASSROOM?
>> I DON'T KNOW THE DETAILS.
OUR CRIME SCENE
INVESTIGATORS ALONG WITH
STATE POLICE ARE DOING WHAT
THEY NEED TO DO WHICH IS
PIECE TOGETHER THE INCIDENT.
I'M SURE THERE WILL BE MUCH
MORE DETAILED INFORMATION AT
1:00 FOR EVERYBODY BUT
OBVIOUSLY IN THE AREA A VERY
SCARY SITUATION FOR ALL
PARENTS IN THE GREATER
DANBURY AREA.
JENNA: WE WANT TO ASK YOU ON
OUR SCREEN.
WE HAVE REPORTS OF MULTIPLE
FATALITIES FROM A LOCAL
NEWSPAPER.
WE'VE BEEN ABLE TO CONFIRM
THROUGH LOCAL OFFICIALS, THE
ASSOCIATED PRESS, THAT THE
GUNMAN IS DEAD.
DO YOU KNOW OF ANY OTHER
FATALITIES?
>> THERE ARE MULTIPLE
FATALITIES AND THE GUNMAN IS
DEAD, THAT'S CORRECT.
JENNA: THE MULTIPLE
FATALITIES, AGAIN WE CAN'T
IDENTIFY THE PEOPLE --
>> I CAN'T.
JENNA: OF COURSE.
WE UNDERSTAND.
WE WANT TO BE RESPECTFUL OF
THAT.
MR. MAYOR, WE APPRECIATE THE
INFORMATION YOU CAN PROVIDE
TO US.
CAN YOU TAKE US BACK TO WHAT
YOU DO KNOW TRANSPIRED THIS
MORNING, PERHAPS GIVE US AN
IDEA OF WHAT HAPPENED EARLY
ON?
>> WELL, OBVIOUSLY THE
SHOOTING TOOK PLACE EARLIER
THIS MORNING.
I WILL SAY NEWTOWN, THE TOWN
OF NEWTOWN, THEIR
ADMINISTRATIVE TEAM DID A
TREMENDOUS JOB MANAGING A
VERY DIFFICULT SITUATION.
THEY'RE OBVIOUSLY VERY TIED
UP RIGHT NOW AND WILL BE
TALKING A LITTLE LATER WHAT
THE STEPS THEY TOOK.
EVERY COMMUNITY SINCE 9/11
IN THIS AREA HAS AN ACTION
PLAN, WHETHER RELATES TO
SCHOOL SHOOTER OR MASS
CASUALTY, EVENT.
WE DRILL IT ALL THE TIME.
WE PRACTICE IT ALL THE TIME.
THE KIDS PRACTICE IT ALL THE
TIME.
THAT'S WHY WE DO THESE
THINGS WITH TRAGIC
SITUATIONS.
WE'RE READY FOR THEM.
JENNA: WE SEE YOUR RESPONSE
BY THE WAY.
THE RESPONSE LOOKS
OVERWHELMING ON THE GROUND,
WITH STATE AND LOCAL POLICE.
HAVE YOU HEARD OF ANY MOTIVE
FOR THE SHOOTING?
>> ALL THAT IS OPEN FOR
INVESTIGATION.
THAT IS SOMETHING WE'LL FIND
OUT AS THE AFTERNOON GOES
ON.
JENNA: GETTING BACK TO
FATALITIES AT THIS TIME,
WHAT CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT
THE FATALITIES?
CAN YOU GIVE US ANY
INFORMATION ON WHETHER OR
NOT IT IS ADMINISTRATION,
TEACHERS, CHILDREN, ANYTHING?
>> I'M SORRY, I CAN'T.
I JUST CAN'T.
>> THAT'S OKAY.
WE UNDERSTAND.
OUR VIEWERS HAVE BEEN SO
PATIENT WITH US FOR THE LAST
SEVERAL HOURS AND YOU HAVE
AS WELL BECAUSE IT HAS BEEN
A VERY CHAOTIC SITUATION.
I WANT TO POINT OUT TO OUR
VIEWERS, OFTEN TIMES,
MR. MAYOR, YOU KNOW THIS AS
WELL, SHE IS SHOOTINGS
HAPPEN IN HIGH SCHOOLS.
WHEN YOU HAVE HIGH SCHOOLS
YOU HAVE STUDENTS, THEY ARE
TEXTING, TWEETING ON
FACEBOOK.
THERE IS LOT OF
COMMUNICATION RIGHT AWAY.
WE HAVE TO REMIND OUR
VIEWERS THESE ARE LITTLE
KIDS, KINDERGARTEN THROUGH
FOURTH GRADE.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
JENNA: AT THIS SCHOOL.
THAT DEFINITELY AFFECTS
INFORMATION.
JON YOU HAVE QUESTIONS FOR
THE MAYOR AS WELL.
JON: PART OF THE FRUSTRATION
FOR PARENTS, THE POLICE HAD
TO SWEEP THE SCHOOL AND
INSURE THERE IS NO OTHER
DANGER.
HAS THAT BEEN COMPLETED AT
THIS POINT AS FAR AS YOU
KNOW?
>> THEY'RE STILL WORKING ON
A SWEEP.
THAT IS THE CORRECT
PROTOCOL.
THAT IS DRILLED WITH EACH
POLICE DEPARTMENT ON THE
AREA.
THERE ARE MAPS OF EVERY
SCHOOL, CLOSET, BUILDING.
THEY TAKE A VERY, PRAGMATIC
APPROACH AND GO THROUGH EACH
OF THEIR OWN CLASS TO --
PLACE IS SECURE.
SO YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT,
THEY'RE WORKING ON THAT RIGHT
NOW, AND THAT'S THE APPROPRIATE
PROCEDURE GOING FORWARD.
JON: SOME OF THE EARLY REPORTS
SUGGESTED THERE MIGHT BE
MULTIPLE GUNMEN.
HAVE YOU SEEN ANYTHING TO VERIFY
THAT, OR ARE WE JUST TALKING
ABOUT ONE SHOOTER HERE WHO IS
DEAD?
>> I'VE HEARD THAT SAME REPORT.
I DON'T HAVE ANY INFORMATION
THAT WOULD EITHER CONFIRM, YOU
KNOW, OR DISPEL THAT REPORT AT
THIS TIME.
IT'S AN ACTIVE, VERY ACTIVE
INVESTIGATION.
STATE POLICE TAKE THE LEAD ALONG
THE NEWTOWN POLICE DEPARTMENT
AND, OBVIOUSLY, OUR POLICE
DEPARTMENT'S PROVIDING ANY HELP
NECESSARY.
JENNA: WE'VE HEARD THAT SOME OF
THE FAMILIES ARE BEING TOLD TO
GO TO A LOCAL FIREHOUSE.
>> YEP.
JENNA: CAN YOU GIVE US A STATUS
REPORT, HAVE FAMILIES BEEN
REUNITED WITH THEIR CHILDREN, OR
IS IT STILL A PROCESS OF THEM
GOING RIGHT NOW?
>> IT'S MY UNDERSTANDING THAT
MOST OF THE CHILDREN HAVE BEEN
REUNITED WITH FAMILIES.
THEY HAD, AGAIN, MY HAT GOES OFF
TO NEWTOWN.
THEY DID A TREMENDOUS JOB IN
MANAGING A VERY DIFFICULT
SITUATION.
THEY HAD, YOU KNOW, A PLAN IN
PLACE, AN EVACUATION PLAN IN
PLACE, AND THEY FOLLOWED IT TO
THE T, IT WORKED.
THEY WERE ABLE TO HOLD THE
STUDENTS AND PROTECT THE
STUDENTS WHILE THIS CATASTROPHIC
EVENT WAS GOING ON, AND I'M
PRETTY SURE EVERYBODY'S BEEN
REUNITED IN TERMS OF CHILDREN
AND FAMILIES.
JENNA: I'M GETTING SOME MORE
BREAKING NEWS INTO OUR NEWSROOM
FROM YOUR LOCAL NEWSPAPER, THE
HARTFORD CURRENT, THAT SAYS THAT
THE SHOOTING TOOK PLACE INSIDE
THE KINDERGARTEN CLASSROOM.
CAN YOU CONFIRM THAT FOR US?
>> I CANNOT.
JENNA: OKAY.
MR. MAYOR, WHAT DO YOU THINK'S
IMPORTANT FOR YOU AS WE TAKE A
LOOK AT THIS COMMUNITY, AGAIN, A
K-4 SCHOOL, NEARLY 700 STUDENTS.
HAVE YOU EVER HAD SOMETHING LIKE
THIS HAPPEN BEFORE IN THE
COMMUNITY?
>> YOU KNOW, THIS IS A VERY
QUIET, PEACEFUL AREA OF THE
COUNTRY.
NO, WE HAVEN'T.
BUT I WILL SAY THAT THERE'S A
REASON WHY WE HAVE ALL THESE
EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT PLANS AND
THEY WORK, AND THIS IS THE
REASON WHY WE EVEN DRILL WITH
KINDERGARTEN STUDENTS ABOUT HOW
TO EVACUATE THE BUILDING
APPROPRIATELY.
THIS IS WHY.
SO WITH THE RIGHT PLANNING, WE
AVOIDED WHAT COULD HAVE BEEN AN
EVEN WORSE, CATASTROPHIC EVENT
THAN WE HAVE HERE, AND THE
PARENTS CAN FEEL COMFORT THAT
THE GREATER COMMUNITY HAVE A
PLAN, THE KIDS KNOW THAT, AND IT
PAYS OFF WHEN YOU HAVE AN AWFUL
SITUATION LIKER -- LIKE THIS.
JENNA: MR. MAYOR, YOU'VE BEEN
MOST GRACIOUS WITH YOUR TIME
DURING A VERY DIFFICULT
SITUATION.
WE SO APPRECIATE THE TIME WITH
YOU AND WISH YOU LUCK THROUGHOUT
THE DAY.
WE'LL, OF COURSE, STAY CLOSE FOR
MORE INFORMATION, BUT THANK YOU
VERY MUCH, SIR.
JON: MARK DOWDEN, THE -- BOWDEN,
THE MAYOR OF DANBURY,
CONNECTICUT.
AN OMINOUS REPORT OF WHAT MAY
HAVE HAPPENED AT THIS SCHOOL,
JUST BEFORE CHRISTMAS, RIGHT IN
THE MIDDLE OF HANUKKAH AND THEN
THIS HAPPENS ON A BEAUTIFUL
FRIDAY MORNING OUTSIDE DANBURY,
CONNECTICUT.
JENNA: IF YOU'RE JUST JOINING US
NOW AT 12 EASTERN TIME, 9:00 ON
THE WEST COAST.
EARLIER THIS MORNING, AROUND
9:40 EAST COAST TIME, A SHOOTER
WALKED INTO THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, AND WE DON'T
KNOW WHERE OR WHAT EXACTLY
TRANSPIRED, BUT THERE WAS A
SHOOTING THAT TOOK PLACE.
ACCORDING TO ONE LOCAL REPORT
THE FIRST
WE'RE HEARING OF THIS, SO WE'RE
GOING TO BE CAREFUL WITH THIS
REPORT -- THAT THE SHOOTING
MIGHT HAVE TAKEN PLACE IN A
KINDERGARTEN CLASSROOM.
ACCORDING TO A MAYOR FROM
DANBURY, MAYOR BOWDEN, HE SAID
THERE ARE THREE VICTIMS AT THE
HOSPITAL.
HE WASN'T ABLE TO CONFIRM THEIR
STATE, BUT HE DID MENTION THAT
THE INJURIES ARE SERIOUS.
HE ALSO CONFIRMED FOR US ONE
REPORT THAT THERE ARE MULTIPLE
FATALITIES.
WE DO NOT KNOW THE IDENTITIES,
WE DO NOT KNOW THE AGE.
THESE ARE CERTAINLY DEVELOPMENTS
AND DETAILS THAT WILL TRANSPIRE
OVER THE NEXT SEVERAL HOURS.
POLICE WERE CALLED TO THE SCENE
RIGHT AWAY, IT'S LOCAL POLICE,
STATE POLICE, AND IF YOU CAN SEE
ON THE CORNER OF YOUR SCREEN
RIGHT THERE, THERE'S A CAR.
YOU SEE THE YELLOW TAPE KIND OF
MARKED OFF AROUND THAT CAR.
WE DON'T KNOW ANY INFORMATION
ABOUT THAT CAR, BUT WE DO KNOW A
SHOOTER ENTERED THE BUILDING
RIGHT AFTER, JON, THE SCHOOL
APPARENTLY LOCKS ITS DOORS IN
THE MORNING, AND THAT'S PART OF
THEIR SAFETY PROCEDURE FOR THE
NEARLY 700 STUDENTS IN THAT
SCHOOL.
JON: OUR FOX AFFILIATE, WFSB
FROM HARTFORD, HAS BEEN WORKING
THE STORY SINCE IT BROKE THIS
MORNING.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE YOU THERE
NOW AND LISTEN TO SOME OF THEIR
REPORTING AS IT COMES IN LIVE.
>> Reporter: HEIGHTENED STATE
OF SECURITY AT THEIR SCHOOLS AS
WELL UPON HEARING THIS AND, OF
COURSE, ONE OF THE BIG THINGS
THAT WE ARE WAITING TO HEAR AND
THAT POLICE ARE WORKING ON RIGHT
NOW IS WHAT POSSIBLE MOTIVE
COULD BE BEMIND THIS SHOOT --
BEHIND THIS SHOOTING AT THIS
SCHOOL.
WE DO KNOW AT LEAST ONE OTHER
PERSON OTHER THAN THE GUNMAN HAS
BEEN SHOT, AND THE GUNMAN IS
DEAD AT THIS POINT.
>> Reporter: AND AS OUR SISTER
STATION IN NEW YORK CITY IS
SAYING, AT LEAST THREE PEOPLE
WERE INJURED, TWO CHILDREN AND
ONE ADULT.
ALL THREE HAVE BEEN TAKEN TO
DANBURY HOSPITAL, BUT THEY ALSO
SAY THEY'RE LOOKING FOR A CAR,
MAROON OR RED-COLORED VEHICLE
WITH THE BACK WINDOW BLOWN OUT.
THAT IS SOMETHING THAT WCBS OUT
OF NEW YORK CITY IS REPORTING.
AGAIN, WE'RE JUST TRYING TO GIVE
YOU THE INFORMATION THAT'S
COMING IN FROM SO MANY DIFFERENT
SOURCES, CHOOSING THE ONES WE
KNOW TO BE THE MOST RELIABLE
WITH THE ASSOCIATED PRESS AND
OUR SISTER STATIONS, WCBS.
THEY SAY LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS HAVE CONFIRMED THIS TO
THEM.
>> Reporter: AND TO GIVE YOU
AN IDEA HOW CHAOTIC THE SCENE AS
YOU LOOK AND SEE THE RESOURCES
AT THE REAR OF THE FIREHOUSE
THAT'S BEING USED AS A STAGING
AREA, JUST TO GIVE YOUEN AN
IDEA, ROBERT GOULSTON REPORTED
THAT POLICE OFFICERS CAME OUT OF
THE WOODS ESCORTING A GENTLEMAN
WHO WAS TELLING PEOPLE THERE I
HAD NOTHING TO DO WITH THIS.
BUT THAT'S THE KIND OF RESPONSE
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT, WHERE
ANYONE FOUND IN THIS AREA WAS AT
LEAST QUESTIONED BY POLICE, AND
THEY WANT TO TALK TO ANYONE WHO
WAS THERE.
POLICE ALSO JUST AS WE ARE
WORKING RIGHT NOW TO TRY AND GET
A HANDLE ON ACT -- EXACTLY WHAT
HAS HAPPENED.
IT LOOKS LIKE THE HELICOPTER
PICTURES ARE HAVING A LITTLE
FREEZE-UP, BUT THAT WAS A SHOT
OF THE FIREHOUSE WHERE THIS TOOK
PLACE, AND YOU CAN GET A BETTER
IDEA OF WHAT THAT SCENE LOOKS
LIKE.
THE FIREHOUSE IS JUST ABOVE THAT
LABEL THAT SAYS DICKENSON DRIVE
AT THE MIDDLE OF THE MAP.
THE BUILDING YOU CAN SEE AT THE
UPPER LEFT OF THAT LABEL IS THAT
FIREHOUSE, AND THAT IS WHERE
ROBERT HAS BEEN GOING LIVE,
REPORTING LIVE FOR US THIS
MORNING, AND THEN YOU SEE THE
LONG DRIVEWAY, THE WHITE
BUILDING -- THE FIREHOUSE -- THE
LONG DRIVEWAY LEADING INTO THAT
SCHOOL, AND THAT'S WHERE POLICE
ARE SWARMING.
>> Reporter: POLICE ARE
EFFORTING TO HAVE A NEWS
CONFERENCE, 1:00.
WE UNDERSTAND THEY'RE GOING
ABOUT TWO MILES AWAY, AND THEY
REALIZE THAT THE PUBLIC IS
CERTAINLY WANTING TO KNOW AS
MUCH AS POSSIBLE, ESPECIALLY
PARENTS.
A REVERSE 911 CALL HAS ALREADY
GONE OUT TO THE RESIDENTS OF
NEWTOWN INFORMING THEM OF THIS
SCHOOL SHOOTING AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
DANBURY TIMES IS REPORTING THAT
STUDENTS STARTED TO HEAR THE
GUNSHOTS DURING THE MORNING
ANNOUNCEMENTS.
>> Reporter: I'M SORRY TO
INTERRUPT YOU, CBS IS NOW
REPORTING THAT AT LEAST ONE
CHILD AT THE SCHOOL HAS DIED AS
A RESULT OF THIS SHOOTING AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, AT LEAST ONE
CHILD AT THAT SCHOOL HAS DIED IN
THIS SHOOTING.
SO, OBVIOUSLY, WE HAD FEARED
THAT THAT WOULD BE THE NEWS THAT
WE WOULD BE GETTING, THAT THERE
WAS MORE CASUALTIES.
WE KNOW THAT THE GUNMAN IS DEAD,
AND NOW WE ARE HEARING CBS NEWS
CONFIRMING AT LEAST ONE CHILD
THERE DEAD AS WELL, JUST
HEARTBREAKING NEWS.
>> Reporter: ABSOLUTELY
HEARTBREAKING.
LET'S GO LIVE TO ROBERT THERE ON
THE SCENE.
ROBERT?
>> Reporter: YEAH, THERE IS A
LOT OF TENSENESS HERE AND A LOT
OF CONFUSION.
PARENTS JUST SHOWED UP HERE, OF
COURSE, AFTER THEY STARTED
GETTING INFORMATION THAT THERE
WAS SOME SORT OF SHOOTING
INCIDENT HERE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AND JUST LOOK AROUND, YOU CAN
SEE ALL OF THE EMERGENCY
VEHICLES, ALL OF THE
PARTICIPANTS MIXED -- PARENTS
MIXED IN TOGETHER.
OF COURSE, THE POLICE ARE TRYING
TO SECURE THE SCENE OVER AT THE
SCHOOL.
WE DO KNOW THAT THERE HAVE BEEN
AT LEAST SEVERAL PEOPLE SHOT.
PARENTS ARE GETTING INFORMATION
FROM EMERGENCY OFFICIALS THAT
ONE OF THOSE PEOPLE SHOT MAY BE
THE PRINCIPAL.
WE ARE STILL TRYING TO CONFIRM
THAT.
STATE POLICE ARE STAGING AN AREA
ABOUT TWO MILES FROM HERE WHERE
THEY WILL BE DOING A NEWS
CONFERENCE TO GET OUT SOME
OFFICIAL INFORMATION.
LIEUTENANT PAUL ADVANCE WILL BE
THE ONE -- PAUL VANCE WILL BE
LEADING THAT IN THE NEXT 20-30
MINUTES.
OF COURSE, WE WILL BE AT THAT
NEWS CONFERENCE.
BUT RIGHT NOW OVER AT THE SCHOOL
PARENTS JUST CONFUSED.
WE'RE HEARING THAT, THEY'RE VERY
TENSE.
AS WE WERE SHOWING UP, A LOT OF
THE PARENTS WERE WALKING OUT
WITH THEIR CHILDREN, VERY YOUNG
CHILDREN, THIRD, FOURTH GRADERS,
AND THEY WERE, OF COURSE, VERY
EMOTIONAL.
A LOT OF THEM WERE CRYING.
ONE PARENT TELLING US THAT HIS
CHILD TOLD HIM THAT SOMEBODY
WALKED INTO THE CLASSROOM AND
SHOT THE TEACHER.
THAT'S JUST SOME OF THE
INFORMATION.
WE ASKED THAT PARENT HOW YOUR
CHILD'S DOING, HE WAS RUNNING UP
THE STREET SAYING I DON'T KNOW
AT THIS POINT.
SO THEY'RE STILL TRYING TO
FIGURE OUT THAT.
THERE'S A LOT OF INFORMATION
THAT'S COMING OUT.
AGAIN, THE NEWS CONFERENCE WILL
BE HAPPENING ABOUT TWO MILES
FROM HERE.
WE HAVE A CREW THERE, WE'LL BE
GETTING THAT INFORMATION VERY
SHORTLY AND HOPEFULLY TO SHED
SOME LIGHT, LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE TELLING US THIS IS GOING
TO BE ONE OF THE WORST SHOOTING
INCIDENTS THAT WE'VE SEEN IN
THIS STATE IN A VERY LONG TIME,
THOSE WERE DIRECT WORDS FROM
HIM.
BUT RIGHT NOW NEWTOWN POLICE
HERE TRYING TO WORK WITH THE
PARTICIPANTS.
IT SEEM -- PARENTS.
IT SEEMS THAT STATE POLICE ARE
ACTUALLY HANDLING THE
INVESTIGATION.
WE HAVE ALSO SEEN FEDERAL AGENTS
HERE INCLUDING FROM THE ATF.
THERE'S A LOT OF HEAVY WEAPONRY
THAT'S BEING USED TO GO INTO
THERE.
WE ALSO ARE HEARING REPORTS THAT
AT LEAST ONE OF THE GUNMAN
FINISH IF THERE ARE, IF THERE IS
JUST ONE, MAYBE MORE -- WAS SHOT
AND KILLED.
WE DON'T KNOW IF THAT WAS
SELF-INFLICTED, OR IF HE WAS
SHOT DURING THE INITIAL
RESPONSE.
EXCUSE ME, LIVE RIGHT NOW YOU
CAN SEE SOME OF THE AMBULANCES
LEAVING THE AREA.
THEY'RE COMING OUT OF THE
SCHOOL, AND WE KNOW THAT SEVERAL
PEOPLE WERE INJURED IN THIS, AND
RIGHT NOW WE'RE JUST TRYING TO
FIGURE OUT EXACTLY WHO.
WE'VE TALKED TO A WOMAN, THEY DO
NOT HAVE DETAILS ON WHO WAS
ACTUALLY SHOT, BUT THERE ARE
SOME REPORTS THAT THERE HAVE
BEEN AT LEAST TWO WITH
FATALITIES, MAYBE MORE.
AGAIN, LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE
TELLING ME THIS IS GOING TO BE
ONE OF THE WORST SHOOTINGS
THEY'VE SEEN IN A VERY LONG
TIME, AND CAN THAT NEWS
CONFERENCE IS SUPPOSED TO HAPPEN
MOMENTARILY ABOUT TWO MILES FROM
HERE, AND WE DO HAVE A CREW
THERE, AND WE WILL BE BRINGING
THAT TO YOU LIVE.
FOR NOW, CHANNEL 3 EYEWITNESS
NEWS.
>> Reporter: ROBERT, THANK
YOU.
>> Reporter: SETTING THE SCENE
THERE --
JON: THOSE ARE LYE REPORTS
COMING FROM OUR FOX AFFILIATE,
WSFB IN HARTFORD, CONNECTICUT,
AND AGAIN, ONLY O NOW WORDS
ABOUT THE SITUATION THAT'S
UNFOLDED THIS MORNING IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
YOU CAN IMAGINE HOW TERRIFIED
THE PARENTS ARE TO HEAR THAT
THERE ARE REPORTS THAT A CHILD
OR PERHAPS MORE THAN ONE CHILD
HAS BEEN SHOT IN THIS TERRIBLE
EVENT THIS MORNING WHEN A GUNMAN
APPARENTLY WALKED INTO A SCHOOL,
OPENED FIRE PERHAPS IN THE
KINDERGARTEN CLASSROOM.
AND AUTHORITIES ARE APPARENTLY
SAYING IT IS ONE OF THE, IT'S
GOING TO BE ONE OF THE WORST
MULTIPLE SHOOTING EVENTS IN
CONNECTICUT HISTORY.
JENNA: IT'S INTERESTING, JON,
HERE WE ARE NEARING THREE HOURS
OF WATCHING THIS STORY DEVELOP,
AND FOR THE FIRST FEW HOURS WE
HAD NO REPORTS OF ANY FATALITIES
OTHER THAN THE GUNMAN, AND VERY
QUICKLY THE SITUATION HAS
CHANGED WHERE WE HAVE LEARNED
NOW OF MULTIPLE FATALITIES AND
GETTING SOME MORE DETAILS ABOUT
WHO MAY HAVE BEEN TARGETED OR
AFFECTED BY THIS SHOOTER.
ACCORDING TO A LOCAL NEWSPAPER,
THE ARTFORD CURRENT -- WHICH
WE'VE BEEN RELYING ON HEAVILY
FOR SOME OF THE LATEST REPORTING
OUT OF THE AREA -- WE'RE GETTING
A PICTURE FROM SOME OF THE
CHILDREN ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
INSIDE OF THE SCHOOL.
ONE 8-YEAR-OLD TELLING THE PAPER
THAT POLICE WERE CHECKING
EVERYBODY INSIDE THE SCHOOL
BEFORE THEY WERE ESCORTED TO THE
FIREHOUSE, AND THEY TOLD THE
CHILDREN THEY HAD TO WALK WITH A
PARTNER.
THAT WAS ONE SCENE BY ONE THIRD
GRADER AT THE SCHOOL.
ANOTHER CHILD LEAVING THE SCHOOL
AS THEY WERE LEAVING SAID THERE
WAS SHATTERED GLASS EVERYWHERE.
A POLICE OFFICER APPARENTLY RAN
INTO THE CLASS ROOM WHERE THIS
STUDENT WAS AND TOLD THEM
SIMILARLY TO RUN OUTSIDE --
SIMPLY RUN OUTSIDE AND KEEP
RUNNING UNTIL THEY REACH THE
FIREHOUSE.
THE FIREHOUSE IS KEY.
YOU MAY HAVE SEEN IT IN A FEW OF
OUR SHOTS, IT'S WHERE THE LOCAL
AUTHORITIES ARE TELLING THE
PARENTS TO GO WHERE THEY CAN BE
REUNITED WITH SOME OF THE
STUDENTS THERE.
AND THIS IS AN ONGOING PROCESS,
PARENTS BEING REUNITED WITH
STUDENTS.
YET WE'RE WAITING ON DETAILS
ABOUT THE INJURIES AND ALSO THE
FATALITIES THAT WE'RE JUST
LEARNING ABOUT.
JON: AGAIN, IT'S STILL
DEVELOPING THERE.
OUTSIDE DANBURY, CONNECTICUT, A
PLACE CALLED NEWTOWN, AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, K-4 GRADES.
ALL OF THE FRONT OFFICE STAFF AS
FAR AS WE CAN TELL ARE FEMALES.
THE PRINCIPAL, THE VICE
PRINCIPAL, SOME OF THE SCHOOL
LEADERSHIP, ALL WOMEN.
WHETHER THAT FIGURES INTO WHAT
HAPPENED HERE, WE DON'T YET
KNOW.
BUT WE'RE CONTINUING TO KEEP AN
EYE ON THE SITUATION.
WE'LL GET MORE DEVELOPING, MORE
DETAILS AS THEY DEVELOP, TRY THE
WRING YOU -- BRING YOU THE VERY
LATEST JUST AHEAD ON "HAPPENING.
NOW" N.
Clear, HUH?
I'M NOT JUICE OR FANCY WATER.
I'VE GOTINE GRAMS OF PROTEIN.
THAT'S THREE TIMES MORE THAN ME!
[ Female Announcer ]
Ensure Clear.
NINE GRAMS PROTEIN. ZERO FAT.
IN BLUEBERRY/POMEGRANATE
AND PEACH.
BUT I'M STILL STUBBED UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus Liquid Gels
SPEEDS RELIEF
TO YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A DECONGESTANT
FOR YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
THANKS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Female Announcer ]
Almost nothing can dampen
a baby's mood,
when he wakes up dry
in Pampers.
Unlike other diapers,
Pampers has 3 absorbent layers,
for up to 12 hours
of protection overnight,
and more beautiful mornings.
♪
Pampers. Peaceful Nights.
Playful Days.
JENNA: WE GET YOU BACK TO
CONNECTICUT AS WE LEARN MORE
ABOUT THAT BREAKING SITUATION
THERE AND THE SCHOOL SHOOTING N.
THE MEANTIME, WANT TO TURN TO
WASHINGTON, D.C. AND THE LATEST
NEWS THERE AS WE GET MORE
FALLOUT FROM THE DEADLY
CONSULATE ATTACK IN LIBYA.
THERE ARE CONFLICTING REPORTS ON
WHETHER SECRETARY OF STATE
CLINTON WILL ACTUALLY TESTIFY TO
A HOUSE COMMITTEE ON THAT AMBUSH
THAT KILLED FOUR AMERICANS
INCLUDING OUR AMBASSADOR.
SECRETARY OF STATE CLINTON WAS
EXPECTED TO FACE THE HOUSE
FOREIGN AFFAIRS COMMITTEE NEXT
WEEK, BUT NOW THE STATE
DEPARTMENT IS SAYING MAYBE NOT.
CHIEF INTELLIGENCE CORRESPONDENT
CATHERINE HERRIDGE IS LIVE IN
WASHINGTON WITH MORE DETAILS.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING.
REALLY THREE KEY DEVELOPMENTS
THIS MORNING, THE REPUBLICAN
CHAIR OF THE HOUSE INTELLIGENCE
COMMITTEE HAS SAID HE BELIEVES
THERE WAS, QUOTE, GROSS
NEGLIGENCE ON BEHALF OF THE
STATE DEPARTMENT FOR FAILING TO
ADEQUATELY PROTECT THE
AMBASSADOR.
AS WE FIRST REPORTED HERE ON
FOX, THERE WAS AN EMERGENCY
MEETING IN BENGHAZI, AND AT THAT
MEETING THEY SENT A CABLE
WARNING HILLARY CLINTON'S OFFICE
IN WASHINGTON THAT THEY COULD
NOT WITHSTAND A COORDINATED
ATTACK AND THAT THERE WERE AT
LEAST TEN ISLAMIST MILITIAS OR
al-QAEDA GROUPS TRAINING IN
BENGHAZI, AND THEY ASKED FOR
MORE ASSISTANCE.
THOSE REQUESTS WERE TURNED COULD
BE AND -- TURNED DOWN AND, IN
FACT, THE SECURITY PRESENCE WAS
FURTHER DRAWN DOWN AFTER THAT
EMERGENCY MEETING.
NUMBER TWO, THERE'S A BACK AND
FORTH OVER THE APPEARANCE NEXT
WEEK OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE.
BOTH OF THE RELEVANT COMMITTEES
ARE EXPECTING HER ON THURSDAY,
THOUGH THE STATE DEPARTMENT IS
SUGGESTING THAT THE DATE MAY
SLIDE ARGUING THAT SHE IS NOT
REQUIRED TO TESTIFY OR WOULD NOT
ANTICIPATE TESTIFYING UNTIL THIS
INTERNAL REVIEW CALLED AN
ACCOUNTABILITY REVIEW BOARD OR
ARB IS COMPLETE.
AND THEN THE LAST DEVELOPMENT
WHICH I THINK IS EXTREMELY
SIGNIFICANT IS BASED ON THESE
REGULATIONS.
THESE REGULATIONS COVER THIS
INTERNAL STATE DEPARTMENT
INVESTIGATION.
BASED ON THESE REGULATIONS,
THERE DOES NOT APPEAR TO BE ANY
REQUIREMENT FOR THE COMPLETE,
UNVARNISHED REPORT TO BE SENT TO
CONGRESS WHEN IT'S COMPLETE.
THERE ONLY APPEARS TO BE A
REQUIREMENT FOR HILLARY CLINTON
TO PROVIDE TO CONGRESS HER
SUMMARY OR BULLET POINTS, IF YOU
WILL, OF THAT REPORT, AND THAT
HAS TO BE DONE WITHIN A 90-DAY
PERIOD.
SO THE QUESTION IS WHETHER THERE
WILL BE A MOVE BY CONGRESS TO
SUBPOENA SECRETARY OF STATE
CLINTON TO TESTIFY IF NECESSARY
AND WHETHER THEY WILL PUSH FOR
THE RESULT, UNVARNISHED REPORT
IF NECESSARY.
JENNA: CATHERINE, THANK YOU.
JON: MORE ON THIS WITH
REPUBLICAN SENATOR BOB CORKER.
HE WAS OPPOSED TO AMBASSADOR
RICE'S POSSIBLE NOMINATION AND
JOINS US NOW.
SO SHE HAS WITHDRAWN HER NAME
FOR CONSIDERATION.
DOES THAT IN ANY WAY CHANGE THE
INVESTIGATION INTO WHAT HAPPENED
IN BENGHAZI, SENATOR?
>> OH, I DON'T THINK SO.
I THINK CERTAINLY SUSAN RICE HAD
NOTHING TO DO WITH THE SECURITY.
I THINK MOST OF US JUST THOUGHT
THAT SHE WAS A LITTLE BIT MORE
OF A POLITICAL OPERATIVE THAN
SHE WAS A PRINCIPAL AND HAD
CONCERNS ABOUT HER SERVICE.
I NEVER THOUGHT SHE WAS GOING TO
BE APPOINTED, BY THE WAY, OR AT
LEAST I HAVEN'T FOR SOME TIME
BECAUSE I THINK THE WHITE HOUSE
WAS ABLE TO SEE THE RECEPTION
THAT SHE GOT THERE.
BUT, LOOK, BENGHAZI, I WAS ABLE
TO YESTERDAY SEE THE FOOTAGE
FROM THE DRONE AS FAR AS WHAT
HAPPENED ON THE GROUND.
I WAS ABLE TO ALSO SEE FROM
SECURITY CAMERAS THE GROUPS THAT
WERE COMING IN.
I DO THINK THAT WE WILL
CONTINUE -- THERE'S NO QUESTION
WE'RE GOING TO CONTINUE TO FORCE
A LOOK AT THE SECURITY MEASURES
THERE BECAUSE THE WAY FOLKS WERE
ABLE TO COME INTO OUR COMPOUND
WITH SUCH EASE IN AN AREA THAT
IS TOTALLY CONTROLLED BY
MILITIAS, I THINK, IS SOMETHING
THAT EVERY AMERICAN WANTS US TO
MAKE SURE WE PURSUE TO ITS END.
AND I DO THINK SECRETARY CLINTON
WILL END UP TESTIFYING, AND I
HOPE THAT THE ARB IS READY FOR,
READY THURSDAY FOR HER TO COME
IN AND DO THAT.
I MEAN, THAT'S WHAT WE EXPECT,
AND I THINK SHE WILL COME BEFORE
US.
JON: PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS SAID
THESE WERE UNFAIR AND MISLEADING
ATTACKS ON HIS U.N. AMBASSADOR
AND SUGGESTED THAT THE POLITICS
OF THE MOMENT PLAYED A ROLE
HERE.
>> YEAH.
JON: WHAT DO YOU SAY TO THAT?
WELL, I DO THINK THE POLITICS OF
THE MOMENT PLAYED A ROLE, AND
THEY PLAYED A ROLE WITH
AMBASSADOR RICE COMING ON FIVE
SUNDAY MORNING PROGRAMS AND
ACTING VERY MUCH LIKE A
POLITICAL OPERATIVE.
AND I'VE TRIED TO MOVE ONIONED
THAT, JON, AND -- MOVE BEYOND
THAT, JON, AND SAY, LOOK, FIRST
OF ALL, I WOULD HAVE GIVEN HER A
FAIR HEARING.
I DO NOT THINK SHE WAS GOING TO
BE CONFIRMED.
IT WASN'T JUST THAT, IT WAS JUST
HER NATURE.
SHE JUST STRIKES MOST OF US WHO
HAVE HAD CONTACT WITH HER
THROUGH THE YEARS MORE AS A
POLITICAL OPERATIVE.
MOST OF US SEE THE OFFICE OF
SECRETARY OF STATE AS SOMETHING
THAT IS ALMOST A FIRST AMONG
EQUALS.
WE WANT SOMEONE WHO IS
INDEPENDENT.
WE KNOW THEY'RE GOING TO SUPPORT
THE PRESIDENT, BUT WE WANT
SOMEONE WHO WILL PULL THE
PRESIDENT IN A DIRECTION THAT'S
GOOD FOR OUR COUNTRY WHEN HE'S
OFF BASE AND MAYBE PURSUING
SOMETHING THAT POLITICALLY IS
MAYBE GOOD FOR HIM BUT NOT GOOD
FOR THE COUNTRY.
WE WANT SOMEBODY MORE
INDEPENDENT, AND I THINK MOST OF
US FELT THAT SHE WAS NOT
INDEPENDENT, MORE OF A POLITICAL
OPERATIVE AND A LOYALIST, AND I
THINK WE'D LIKE -- I KNOW WE
WANT SOMEONE WHO, AGAIN, IS
STEEPED IN THE KNOWLEDGE ABOUT
ISSUES AROUND THE WORLD, BUT IS
GOING TO BE INDEPENDENT ENOUGH
TO PULL THE PRESIDENT IN THE
RIGHT DIRECTION WHEN HE'S OFF
BASE.
JON: ALL INDICATIONS ARETHE FROW
SENATOR, JOHN KERRY.
WOULD YOU SUPPORT HIM?
>> LOOK, I HATE TO SAY ANYTHING
GOOD, JON, ABOUT ANYBODY BECAUSE
IT MAY BE BAD FOR THEM --
[LAUGHTER]
BUT I DO THINK THAT, YOU KNOW,
JOHN KERRY -- I MEAN, IT APPEARS
THAT HE MAY BE THE PERSON.
I THINK HE WOULD BE CONFIRMED
QUICKLY.
I THINK PEOPLE DO VIEW JOHN
KERRY AS SOMEONE WHO IS A
PRINCIPAL, DOES HAVE THAT
INDEPENDENCE.
OBVIOUSLY, HE WAS, HE WOULD
SUPPORT THE PRESIDENT, BUT I
THINK HE HAS THE ABILITY TO PULL
THINGS IN THE RIGHT DIRECTION.
I WILL SAY THAT BEFORE ANYBODY
COMES IN IN THAT POSITION, I DO
HOPE WE'LL GET THIS BENGHAZI
ISSUE BEHIND US.
I THINK IT'S INCUMBENT UPON
SECRETARY CLINTON TO COME CLEAN,
TO ALLOW US TO KNOW EVERYTHING
THAT'S HAPPENED AROUND THIS
ISSUE.
AND I THINK WE NEED TO GET THAT
SWEPT UP AND CLEANED BEFORE WE,
BEFORE WE START A NEW REGIME, IF
WE WILL.
JON: EVERYONE WANTS THOSE
ANSWERS.
REPUBLICAN SENATOR BOB CORKER OF
TENNESSEE, WE APPRECIATE YOU
COMING ON TODAY.
THANK YOU.
JENNA: BACK TO THE BREAKING NEWS
NOW OUT OF CONNECTICUT AND THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING THAT TOOK PLACE
THIS MORNING.
WE'RE LEARNING A LITTLE BIT MORE
POTENTIALLY ABOUT THE SHOOTER IN
ALL OF THIS.
AND UP NEXT, WE TALK TO A PARENT
OF A STUDENT AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WHERE A
SHOOTING TOOK PLACE THIS
MORNING, 9:30, 9:40 EASTERN
TIME.
THE VERY LATEST WITH THAT PARENT
AFTER THIS QUICK BREAK.
JENNA: BACK WITH US NOW WITH
SOME MORE BREAKING NEWS OUT OF
NEWTON, CONNECTICUT.
YOU'RE SEEING A LIVE SHOT OF THE
WOODS, APPARENTLY, THIS IS
PROBABLY BEHIND THE SCHOOL.
I'M STILL GETTING MORE
INFORMATION ABOUT HA THIS LIVE
SHOT -- WHAT THIS LIVE SHOT IS
SHOWING US.
POLICE WERE OUT IN THIS AREA,
AND THEY LOOKED LIKE,
POTENTIALLY, THEY WERE SEARCHING
FOR SOMETHING.
AND I THINK YOU CAN SEE SOME
MOVEMENT IN THE CENTER OF YOUR
SCREEN THERE.
SO I'M GOING TO WAIT FOR SOME
MORE INFORMATION ON THAT SO WE
CAN TELL YOU EXACTLY WHAT'S
GOING ON, HOW THIS FIGURES INTO
THE INVESTIGATION.
IN THE MEANTIME, I WANT TO BRING
IN LISA.
HER DAUGHTER, LEAH, IS 8 YEARS
OLD, A THIRD GRADER AT SANDY
HOOK, AND LISA'S BEEN GRACIOUS
ENOUGH TO JOIN US AND TELL US A
LITTLE BIT ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
THIS MORNING, LISA.
CAN YOU TELL US WHAT YOUR
DAUGHTER TOLD YOU HAPPENED
INSIDE THE SCHOOL?
>> YES.
SHE WAS IN A, UM, A SMALL CLASS,
A READING GROUP, AND THEY
STARTED HEARING, UM, I GUESS
BANGS, AND HER TEACHER -- WHICH
I'M SO GRATEFUL FOR -- THERE WAS
JUST A SMALL GROUP, THEY RUSHED
THE KIDS INTO THE BATHROOM, AND
THEY LOCKED THE DOOR, AND THEY
JUST TOLD THE CHILDREN THAT IT
WAS HAMMERING AND TRIED TO KEEP
THEM CALM.
AND THE NEXT THING I KNOW,
BECAUSE IT'S VERY HARD TO GET A
COMPLETE STORY, THE NEXT THING I
KNOW IS THAT, UM, THE POLICE
CAME IN, AND THEY WERE KNOCKING
ON THE DOOR TO BE LET OUT OF THE
CLASSROOM, AND WHEN THEY WERE,
SHE HAD SEEN GLASS AND BLOOD.
ONE CHILD WAS COVERED IN BLOOD,
BUT I UNDERSTAND THAT CHILD IS
SAFE AND WAS NOT HURT.
IT MUST HAVE BEEN SOMEBODY
ELSE'S.
JENNA: WE'RE HEARING SOME
DIFFERENT REPORTS ABOUT THE
INJURIES AND FATALITIES AND
STILL TRYING TO LEARN MORE
INFORMATION AS WE CAN TO BRING
THAT TO OUR VIEWERS AND EVERYONE
THAT'S WATCHING AND LISTENING
RIGHT NOW, LISA.
WHAT WAS YOUR EXPERIENCE AS A
PARENT?
WHEN KID YOU FIRST -- WHEN DID
YOU FIRST HEAR OF SOMETHING
HAPPENING AT THE SCHOOL, AND
WHAT HAPPENED AFTER THAT?
>> WELL, I WAS -- IT WAS FUNNY,
BECAUSE I WAS ON MY COMPUTER,
AND, UM, I GET BREAKING NEWS,
AND THEY WERE -- THE SCHOOLS
WERE ON LOCKDOWN BECAUSE OF A
SHOOTING IN SANDY HOOK.
AND WHEN I THINK BACK, I THOUGHT
IT WAS THE TOWN.
AND THE NEXT THING I KNOW, I GET
A CALL FROM CARRIE SUMMERS, HER
READING TEACHER, WHO IS MY HERO
RIGHT NOW.
I CAN'T THANK HER ENOUGH FOR
CALLING ME AND TELLING ME THAT
MY DAUGHTER WAS SAFE AND AT THE
FIREHOUSE.
SO THEY BROUGHT THE CHILDREN
FROM THE SCHOOL, THE MAJORITY OF
THEM, TO THE FIREHOUSE, AND
THEY --
JENNA: AND WHAT WAS THE SCENE
LIKE THERE?
>> CHAOTIC, CHAOTIC.
ALL I KNOW IS THAT, UM, I HAD
CHILDREN CRYING, AND I KNEW
THEIR PARENTS, SO I CALLED THEM
ON THEIR CELL, AND ONE PARENT
WAS SCARED ABOUT HER FIRST
GRADER.
SHE COULDN'T FIND -- SO I LOOKED
FOR A TEACHER, AND I COULD NOT
FIND, AND I KNOW I THINK THIS
THIS HAPPENED HA IN FIRST GRADE.
JENNA: WE'RE HEARING A FEW
DIFFERENT REPORTS.
SOME ARE SUGGESTING THE
PRINCIPAL'S OFFICE, SOME ARE
SUGGESTING THE KINDERGARTEN
CLASS.
AS YOU MENTIONED, MAYBE THE
FIRST GRADE.
>> YEAH, I HEARD FIRST GRADE.
JENNA: HAVE YOU HEARD ANYTHING
ELSE?
I KNOW THAT THE PARENTS ARE
PROBABLY TRYING TO COMPARE NOTES
ABOUT, YOU KNOW, WHAT HAPPENED,
WHO DID IT.
HAVE YOU HEARD ANYTHING LIKE
THAT?
>> NO, I HAVE NO IDEA.
I'M WATCHING THE NEWS NOW, AND
IT'S SAYING THAT THE GUNMAN'S
DEAD, AND THE PRINCIPAL MAY HAVE
BEEN SHOT, AND THERE WAS A WOMAN
WITH ALSO SHOT IN THE LEG, BUT I
DON'T KNOW.
JENNA: WE'VE HEARD SOME OF THAT
AS WELL, BUT WE APPRECIATE THAT
BECAUSE IT'S BEEN ONE OF THOSE
SITUATIONS THAT'S BEEN SO
CHAOTIC, AND WE'VE BEEN TRYING
TO PIECE IT TOGETHER FOR OUR
VIEWERS.
HOW IS LEAH DOING RIGHT NOW IN.
>> SHE'S FINE.
I DON'T REALLY THINK THAT SHE
TOTALLY GETS IT, BUT SHE DID
SEE, YOU KNOW, HER -- MORE THAN
I WOULD HAVE LIKED HER TO SEE.
SHE DID TELL ME ABOUT A LITTLE
BOY THAT WAS IN A POLICE
OFFICER'S ARM, AND HE WAS
BLEEDING.
SO -- BUT I DON'T KNOW IF SHE
GETS IT OR --
JENNA: YOU KNOW, ONE OF THE
MAYORS FROM THE NEIGHBORING
TOWN, MAYOR BOWDEN, JOINED US
AND SAID THE SCHOOLS IN THE AREA
REALLY PRACTICE THIS.
HAS YOUR DAUGHTER BEEN IN THE
SCHOOL SINCE KINDERGARTEN?
HAD THEY PRACTICED THE DRILLS,
EVACUATION PROCEDURES?
>> I BELIEVE SO.
IT'S A SAFE SCHOOL, AND I CAN'T
SAY ENOUGH GOOD THINGS ABOUT
TEACHERS AND THE STAFF.
UM, YOU KNOW, IF ANYBODY -- IT
WOULD BE SANDY HOOK SCHOOL THAT
HAS IT DOWN RIGHT BECAUSE,
AGAIN, IT'S THE BEST SCHOOL THAT
YOU CAN -- I'M GRATEFUL FOR MY
KIDS TO GO THERE.
JENNA: HAVE THE TEACHERS OR
AUTHORITIES GIVEN YOU ANY
GUIDANCE OF WHAT TO DO NEXT?
>> NO.
JENNA: HAVE THEY SAID THEY'RE
GOING TO TALK TO YOUR DAUGHTER?
>> NO.
I'M STILL IN A STATE OF SHOCK,
SO I DON'T KNOW THE NEXT STEP.
I DON'T KNOW.
JENNA: IF YOU COULD JUST STAND
BY WITH US FOR ONE MOMENT, LISA,
BUT
BECAUSE I THINK WE'RE GETTING
MORE INFORMATION ABOUT WHAT WE
WERE SEEING ON THE SCREEN THERE
WITH THE WOODS, JON?
JON: ONE -- I WOULD JUST SAY,
JENNA, THAT ONE PARENT TOLD
AUTHORITIES SAID SHE HEARD TWO
BIG BANGS AT THE TIME OF THIS
SHOOTING.
WE ALSO KNOW THAT THE FEDERAL,
THE DEPARTMENT OF ALCOHOL,
TOBACCO AND FIREARMS IS ON THE
SCENE.
THEY HAVE RECOVERED MORE THAN
ONE FIREARM AND, AGAIN, WE WERE
TOLD THAT THE SHOOTER WALKED IN
WITH AT LEAST TWO WEAPONS.
BUT WHETHER THERE IS STILL AN
ACTIVE SEARCH UNDERWAY FOR A
SECOND GUNMAN, THAT'S THE
QUESTION, AND THAT MAY HAVE
SOMETHING TO DO WITH THAT
HELICOPTER AERIAL SHOT OF THE
WOODS OUTSIDE THE SCHOOL.
IT IS A FAIRLY WOODED AREA.
IT'S 60 MILES TO THE NORTH AND
EAST OF NEW YORK CITY AND NOT
HEAVILY POPULATED.
THERE YOU CAN SEE IT APPEARS TO
BE A SEARCH DOG LOOKING AROUND
IN THAT AREA UNDER THAT TREE
NEAR THE SCHOOL.
JENNA: BACK WITH LISA JUST FOR A
MOMENT.
LISA, YOU SAID THIS IS JUST A
SCHOOL YOU APPRECIATE THE
TEACHERS AND LOVE THE EXPERIENCE
THAT YOUR DAUGHTER HAS HAD SO
FAR.
JUST IN GENERAL AS YOU REFLECT,
AND I KNOW YOU'RE STILL IN A
STATE OF SHOCK RIGHT NOW, WHAT
IS NEXT FOR THE SCHOOL?
DO YOU, DO YOU FORESEE RETURNING
YOUR DAUGHTER TO CLASS ON
MONDAY, OR IS THAT, AGAIN, STILL
SOMETHING THAT'S UNKNOWN?
>> YOU KNOW, I DON'T KNOW THE
DETAILS, AND -- NOR DID I EVER
WANT TO GO THROUGH THIS
EXPERIENCE.
SO, AGAIN, I'M IN KIND OF,
AGAIN, JUST I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW.
JENNA: WE CAN UNDERSTAND THAT,
AND I DON'T -- YOU KNOW, IT'S MY
FAULT.
I SHOULDN'T HAVE GOTTEN AHEAD OF
OURSELVES, BECAUSE IT'S STILL A
SITUATION WHERE WE DON'T HAVE A
LOT OF ANSWERS.
LISA, I JUST REALLY APPRECIATE
YOUR PERSPECTIVE, ESPECIALLY AS
A MOTHER IN THE AREA.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR THE TIME.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
JENNA: MORE ON THIS BREAKING
NEWS OUT OF CONNECTICUT WHEN WE
GET BACK.
ANNCR: Some politicians seem to
think Medicare and...
Social Security are just numbers
in a budget.
Well, we worked hard for those
benefits.
We earned them.
And if Washington tries to cram
decisions about the future...
of these programs into a last
minute budget deal...
we'll all pay the price.
AARP is fighting to protect
seniors with responsible...
solutions that strengthen
Medicare and...
Social Security for generations
to come.
We can do better than a last
minute deal...
that would hurt all of us.
JENNA: WE CONTINUE TO FOLLOW
THIS VERY DEVELOPING, CHAOTIC
SITUATION OUT OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
A SCHOOL SHOOTING TOOK PLACE
AROUND 9:40 EASTERN TIME THIS
MORNING.
HARRIS HAS SOME BRAND NEW
INFORMATION FOR US NOW.
>> Reporter: ALL RIGHT.
A COUPLE OF THINGS.
THEY HAVE BROKEN DOWN IN JUST
THE SHORT LITTLE WHILE, JENNA,
THE TRY I CAN'T IMAGINE AREA --
TRIAGE AREA.
THE SECOND DEVELOPMENT IS COMING
FROM ABC NEWS, AND WE ARE
WORKING TO CONFIRM THIS FOR
OURSELVES.
WE KNOW THAT A NEWS CONFERENCE
IS ABOUT -- SCHEDULED ABOUT 24
MINUTES FROM NOW WITH THE
FEWTOWN POLICE DEPARTMENT JOINED
BY FEDERAL OFFICIALS WHO ARE NOW
ON THE SCENE.
ABC NEWS IS REPORTING THROUGH
THOSE FEDERAL LOCAL CONTACTS
THAT THEY HAVE THAT A DOZEN
PEOPLE POSSIBLY HAVE DIED TODAY
HERE.
AGAIN, WE'RE WORKING TO CONFIRM
THAT, AMONG THEM CHILDREN,
ACCORDING TO ABC NEWS.
HERE'S WHAT I CAN TELL YOU.
THE ATF, THE BUREAU OF ALCOHOL,
TOBACCO, FIREARMS AND EXCLUSIVES
IS THERE AT THE SCENE.
THEY HAVE SENT SEVEN AGENTS FROM
THE ATF THERE TO THE SCHOOL IN
CONNECTICUT.
THE AGENTS FROM THE ATF HAVE
REPORTEDLY COLLECTED FIREARMS.
WE'RE NOT TOLD HOW MANY.
BUT THEY ARE NOW WORKING WITH
THE STATE POLICE IN CONNECTICUT
WITH WHOM I'VE SPOKEN WITH TODAY
SO THAT WE KNEW WE HAD MULTIPLE
SHOOTINGS HERE.
WE STILL DON'T KNOW THE
CONFIGURATION, HOW MANY ADULTS,
HOW MANY CHILDREN.
ABC NEWS, OF COURSE, REPORTING
THESE FATALITIES THROUGH THEIR
SOURCES.
WE'RE WORKING WITH OURS NOW TO
TERM IF THIS UP. -- FULL-TERM
THIS UP.
JENNA, WE KNEW EARLY ON IN THIS
STORY THAT THIS WAS ANTICIPATED
TO BE THE WORST IN MANY YEARS
SHOOTING SCENE IN THIS
CONNECTICUT STATE HISTORY.
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WITH
POSSIBLY MORE THAN ONE CRIME
SCENE INSIDE THE SCHOOL THROUGH
WHAT WE'RE LEARNING FROM
REPORTS.
THE PRINCIPAL'S OFFICE, A
KINDERGARTEN CLASSROOM, POSSIBLY
MULTIPLE FIREARMS.
WE KNOW THE ATF IS PICKING THOSE
UP NOW.
CHILDREN AMONG THOSE INJURED,
ACCORDING TO ABC NEWS, CHILDREN
AMONG THOSE KILLED TODAY.
A TERRIBLE SITUATION.
A CODE REDDISH SHOED THROUGHOUT
THE TOWN.
I KNEW THAT EARLIER FROM THE
EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT AGENCY
THERE ON THE GROUND IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
JENNA, JON?
JENNA: HARRIS, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
WANT TO BE VERY CLEAR WITH OUR
VIEWERS, WE HAVE TWO MAJOR ITEMS
CONFIRMED RIGHT NOW WHEN IT
COMES TO THIS SCHOOL SHOOTING,
AND THAT'S ABOUT IT.
WE KNOW THAT THERE'S A SCHOOL
SHOOTING, AND WE KNOW THAT THE
GOOD
GUNMAN IS DEAD.
AS FAR AS THE FATALITIES AND
INJURIES, WE HAVE ZERO DETAILS
ON THAT CONFIRMED.
WE HOPE TO HEAR DIRECTLY FROM
THE STATE AND LOCAL POLICE IN,
HOPEFULLY, AROUND TEN MINUTES,
SO WE WANT TO GET THOSE NEWS
ITEMS CONFIRMED TO YOU, BUT WE
DO NOT WANT TO RUSH ANYTHING AT
THIS TIME.
IT'S SUCH A SENSITIVE STORY.
A SHOOTING AT AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, K-4.
NEARLY 700 STUDENTS THERE.
WE'LL KEEP YOU POSTED AS WE HEAR
MORE.
JON: WELL, "HAPPENING NOW" TO
ONE OF THE BIG POLITICAL STORIES
COMING OUT OF WASHINGTON, IT
DIDN'T TAKE LONG FOR THE BLAME
GAME TO START.
THIS AFTER AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE
WITHDREW HER NAME FROM
CONSIDERATION TO BECOME
SECRETARY OF STATE.
NBC'S WHITE HOUSE CORRESPONDENT
CHUCK TODD WAS QUICK TO BLAME
WHAT HE CALLED CONSERVATIVE
MEDIA.
LISTEN.
>> THERE WERE LEGITIMATE
QUESTIONS TO ASK ABOUT THE
BENGHAZI STORY, BUT THE IDEA
THAT SHE BELONGED IN THE CENTER
OF THOSE ATTACKS NEVER MADE A
LOT OF SENSE.
SHE SORT OF BECAME A VICTIM OF
THIS.
JON: SO WHAT ABOUT THAT?
FAIR?
LET'S CHECK IN WITH OUR NEWS
WATCH PANEL, JUDITH MILLER, A
PULITZER PRIZE-WINNING
INVESTIGATIVE REPORTER AND
KIRSTEN POWERS, A DAILY BEAST
COLUMNIST.
I GUESS CHUCK TODD WOULD HAVE US
BELIEVE THAT SUSAN RICE,
AMBASSADOR RICE'S STATEMENTS ON
THE MORNING SHOWS ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED IN BENGHAZI PLAYED NO
ROLE WHATSOEVER IN HER DECISION
TO WITHDRAW HER NAME FROM
CONSIDERATION, JUDY.
>> WELL, OF COURSE, THIS IS
JUST -- IT'S LUDICROUS.
CHUCK TODD HAS BEEN A GREAT
DEFENDER OF SUSAN RICE, AND I
HAVE BEEN VERY, VERY CRITICAL --
AS YOU KNOW, JON AND KIRSTEN --
OF THE ADMINISTRATION'S HANDLING
OF THE BENGHAZI DISASTER.
BUT I WILL SAY THIS, THE
RESPONSE TO SUSAN RICE, THE
FOCUS ON HER, THE KILLING OF THE
MESSENGER IS, AS JOE SCARBOROUGH
HAS SAID, DISPROPORTIONATE.
AND I FIND IT VERY UNUSUAL THAT
THIS CAMPAIGN, THOUGH LED BY
REPUBLICANS, WAS QUICKLY JOINED
BY LIBERALS AND BY LEFT-WINGERS
WHO ACCUSED SUSAN RICE OF BEING
TOO COZY WITH AFRICAN DICTATORS.
SHE WAS GETTING IT FROM ALL
SIDES.
WHAT REALLY, REALLY OFFENDS ME
IS THE PERSONAL NATURES OF THE
ATTACKS ON HER BY JOURNALISTS
WHO SHOULD HAVE KNOWN BETTER.
MAUREEN DOWD CALLED HER TOO
AMBITIOUS, TOO UNPRINCIPLED FOR
THE COUNTRY.
DANA MILL BANKS SAID THAT SHE
HAD AN ATTITUDE PROBLEM.
THIS KIND OF REACTION WAS
TOTALLY INAPPROPRIATE.
JON: KIRSTEN, WE ALSO HEARD FROM
ANDREA MITCHELL WHO SAID THIS
WAS NOT GOING TO HELP
REPUBLICANS, FORCING A WOMAN OF
COLOR OUT OF THE CONSIDERATION
TO BECOME SECRETARY OF STATE.
WHERE DOES THAT PLAY INTO ALL
THIS?
>> IT'S IRRELEVANT.
IT HAS NOTHING TO DO WITH
ANYTHING.
FIRST OF ALL, WE'VE HAD A WOMAN
AFRICAN-AMERICAN SECRETARY OF
STATE, YOU KNOW, A REPUBLICAN,
ACTUALLY, WHO WAS CONFIRMED BY
THE SAME PEOPLE WHO ARE
CRITICIZING SUSAN RICE.
AND CAN, YOU KNOW, I THINK THAT
THE STORYLINE THAT SOMEHOW --
AND THIS WAS WHAT SUSAN RICE
SAID IN HER WITHDRAWAL -- WAS
THAT SHE SOMEHOW GOT CAUGHT UP
IN PARTISAN POLITICS ISN'T A
TRUE STORY.
BECAUSE AS JUDY JUST SAID, THERE
WERE LIBERALS THAT CAME AFTER
HER IN VERY PERSONAL TERMS.
THE CRITICISMS FROM THE
REPUBLICANS WERE ACTUALLY ABOUT
BENGHAZI, AND, YOU KNOW, THE
CRITICISMS FROM THE LEFT WERE
MUCH MORE PERM, AND I THINK --
PERSONAL, AND I THINK, WAS THE
TURNING POINT.
I THINK IF THE LEFT HADN'T
GOTTEN ON THE BANDWAGON, MAYBE
SHE WOULDN'T HAVE HAD TO
WITHDRAW HER NAME.
SO CLEARLY THE TIDE TURNED
AGAINST HER WHEN YOU HAD A MAJOR
NEW YORK TIMES REPORTER COMING
OUT AGAINST HER, FOR EXAMPLE.
JON: WELL, AND ARE THE MEDIA
REMEMBERING WHAT HAPPENED TO
JOHN BOLTON --
>> EXACTLY.
JON: HE WAS GIVEN A RECESS
APPOINTMENT, AND TRIED -- YOU
KNOW, HIS NAME WAS SUBMITTED TO
THE FULL SENATE FOR
CONFIRMATION, BUT THAT WAS SHOT
DOWN, JUDY.
NOBODY SEEMS TO REMEMBER THAT
THERE WAS MOSTLY PARTISAN
POLITICS INVOLVED IN THAT.
>> I MEAN, IN THE HAS ALWAYS
BEEN PARTISAN, IT'S ALWAYS BEEN
POLITICAL.
NOMINEES OF MAJOR NATIONAL
SECURITY OFFICIALS ARE NOT
EXEMPT FROM POLITICS, BUT THEY
SHOULD BE EXEMPT FROM THE KIND
OF AD HOMINEM, PERSONAL, REALLY
VICIOUS ATTACKS THAT WE SAW
AGAINST SUSAN RICE.
IT WAS COMPLETELY UNCALLED FOR.
THERE WERE REASONS TO OPPOSE HER
ON POLICY GROUNDS.
THE REPUBLICANS PRETTY MUCH
STUCK TO THAT, AND I AGREE WITH
KIRSTEN.
IF THIS HADN'T BEEN JOINED BY
THE LEFT, SHE WOULDN'T HAVE HAD
TO WITHDRAW.
JON: JUDY MILLER AND KIRSTEN
POWERS, OUR NEWS WATCH PANEL,
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
JENNA: ANY MOMENT NOW OUT OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WE EXPECT
TO HEAR FROM STATE AND LOCAL
OFFICIALS ABOUT WHAT TRANSPIRED
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
STILL TRYING TO PIECE TOGETHER
MULTIPLE REPORTS FROM A VARIETY
OF SOURCES ABOUT WHAT ACTUALLY
HAPPENED INSIDE THAT ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL ABOUT THREE HOURS AGO.
AGAIN, REPORTS THAT THERE ARE
MULTIPLE FATALITIES, IDENTITY,
AGE YET UNKNOWN AT THIS TIME.
WE WANT TO BE VERY CAREFUL WITH
THESE REPORTS AS THEY COME INTO
OUR NEWSROOM.
WE DID HEAR FROM ONE PARENT JUST
MOMENTS AGO, A PARENT OF AN
8-YEAR-OLD IN THE A SCHOOL WHO
SAID THAT HER TEACHER WAS ABLE
TO GET THE LITTLE GIRL OUT BY
HIDING AND LOCKING THEMSELVES IN
THE BATHROOM AND THEN BEING ABLE
TO ESCAPE.
JON?
JON: LET'S ALSO TAKE YOU NOW TO
WASHINGTON, D.C. WHERE JAY
CARNEY IS HOLDING HIS DAILY
BRIEFING, TALKING ABOUT THE
SUSAN RICE SITUATION.
LET'S LISTEN IN.
>> SO AT THIS POINT I'D RATHER
JUST INFORM YOU THAT THE
PRESIDENT HAS BEEN INFORMED
ABOUT THE SHOOTING, WAS INFORMED
AT 10:30 AND IS BEING GIVEN
REGULAR UPDATES AS MORE
INFORMATION BECOMES AVAILABLE.
>> WILL WE HEAR FROM HIM TODAY?
>> YOU KNOW, WE'LL JUST HAVE TO
KEEP YOU UPDATED AS MORE
INFORMATION BECOMES AVAILABLE.
>> TWO OTHER TOPICS.
IN THE ABC NEWS INTERVIEW, THE
PRESIDENT WAS ASKED ABOUT THE
LEGALIZATION OF MARIJUANA IN A
COUPLE OF STATES WHERE VOTERS
SOUNDED OFF ON THAT AND
ESSENTIALLY SAID THAT, UM, IT'S
NOT A HIGH PRIORITY FOR HIM, NO
PUN INTENDED, I GUESS, TO GO
AFTER RECREATIONAL USERS.
BUT, OBVIOUSLY, THIS IS A
SERIOUS ISSUE, STATES' RIGHTS
VERSUS FEDERAL RIGHTS.
AND I'M WONDERING IF THERE'S ANY
CONCERN THAT THE PRESIDENT'S
COMMENTS COULD SIGNAL THAT
STATES, YOU KNOW, IT'S OKAY TO
GO AHEAD AND PURSUE YOUR OWN
POLICIES ON MARIJUANA, WE'RE NOT
GOING TO ENFORCE IT AT THE
FEDERAL LEVEL?
JON: ALL RIGHT, WE ARE -- AND MY
APOLOGIES, I THOUGHT THAT JAY
CARNEY WAS GOING TO BE TALKING
ABOUT THE WITHDRAWAL OF SUSAN
RICE FROM CONTENTION TO BE
SECRETARY OF STATE.
HE DID MENTION THAT THE
PRESIDENT WAS INFORMED ABOUT THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTING AND
HAS BEEN STAYING ON TOP OF THE
SITUATION.
HARRIS HAS BREAKING NEWS FOR US
NOW.
>> Reporter: YEAH.
THIS IS JUST COMING INTO OUR
NEWSROOM.
A HOSPITAL IN DANBURY,
CONNECTICUT, WHICH IS NOT
AWFULLY FAR FROM THE SCENE OF
WHERE THE SHOOTING HAPPENED,
ALMOST THREE HOURS AGO NOW, IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, THAT
HOSPITAL SPOKESPERSON SAYING
THAT IT IS ON LOCKDOWN OUT OF AN
ABUNDANCE OF CAUTION AND TO
PROTECT CONFIDENTIALITY OF THE
PATIENTS WHICH HAVE BEEN TAKEN
THERE.
THEY HAVE ONLY THE NEEDED STAFF
AT THAT HOSPITAL AT THIS POINT.
THEY'VE SENT OTHERS AWAY.
SO, BASICALLY, IF YOU ARE NOT
ESSENTIAL TO SAVING LIVES AT
THAT HOSPITAL, YOU'VE BEEN TOLD
TO GO HOME.
THEY HAVE ONLY TREATED THREE
PATIENTS, THEY SAY REPORTEDLY.
AGAIN, THIS IS THE HOSPITAL IN
DANBURY, CONNECTICUT, NOT TOO
FAR FROM THE SCENE IN WHICH
YOU'RE.
WATCHING LIVE ON THE SCREEN NOW,
THAT'S NEWTOWN.
THEY DO NOT ANTICIPATE ANY MORE
PATIENTS TO BE TRANSPORTED TO
THEIR HOSPITAL AT THIS TIME AND,
OF COURSE, WE KNOW THIS, THEY
ARE NOT RELEASING ANY SPECIFIC
INFORMATION ABOUT PATIENT
STATUS, SO ON AND SO FORTH.
NO DISCUSSIONS THAT THEY'VE HAD
WITH ANY OF THE FAMILIES.
I DO WANT TO CAUTION, JENNA SAID
THIS EARLIER, JON, I THINK WE
ALL HAVE, THAT AS INFORMATION
COMES IN ON THIS STORY, WE HAVE
TO BE CAREFUL ABOUT REPORTING
NUMBERS.
WE HAVE SEEN A JUMP IN THE
REPORTS ABOUT HOW MANY PEOPLE
HAVE BEEN SHOT AND POSSIBLY
KILLED TODAY.
I CAN TELL YO FROM DIFFERENT
SOURCES THE NUMBERS ARE ABOVE
12.
SOME OF THEM HAVE THEM AS HIGH
AS IN THE 20s AT THIS POINT.
INJURIES AND FATALITIES.
WE'RE WORKING HERE AT FOX NEWS
TO SHORE THAT UP.
WE WANT TO BE RESPONSIBLE IN
TELLING YOU WHAT WE CAN CONFIRM.
WE ALSO WANT TO TELL YOU
BECAUSE, OF COURSE, WE'RE IN THE
WORLD OF TWITTER AND EVERYTHING
ELSE, YOU MAY BE SEEING IT, THAT
WE'RE SEEING THE SAME REPORTS.
WE'RE CHASING THEM DOWN.
NO DOUBT ABOUT IT, THIS IS A
HORRIBLE SCENE PLAYING OUT IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
BACK TO YOU GUYS.
JON: AND AS YOU WERE JUST
SPEAKING THERE, HARRIS, WE GOT
SOME INFORMATION IN THAT AT
LEAST FIVE CHILDREN ARE DEAD.
THIS HAS BEEN CONFIRMED BY OUR
FOX NEWS PRODUCERS AND CONFIRMED
BY TWO LAW ENFORCEMENT SOURCES,
AT LEAST FIVE CHILDREN DEAD,
FOUR ADULTS DEAD, AND THE
NUMBER, AGAIN, AS HARRIS JUST
MENTIONED, COULD GO HIGHER.
THE ADULT GUNMAN IS ALSO DEAD.
THE INITIAL REPORTS INDICATE HE
DROVE TO THAT SCHOOL FROM NEW
JERSEY.
TWO HANDGUNS WERE RECOVERED FROM
THE SCENE.
THE STATUS, THE MOTIVE HERE
STILL UNKNOWN, ABSOLUTELY NO
INDICATION WHAT THE MOTIVE WAS
ACCORDING TO ONE INVESTIGATOR.
BUT THAT'S GOING TO BE PIECED
TOGETHER IN THE DAYS AND WEEKS
TO COME.
TEACHERS ARE BEING CALLED HEROES
FOR THE WAY THEY RESPONDED,
HAVING LOCKED THEIR CLASSROOM
DOORS TO KEEP THE GUNMAN OUT.
AND APPARENTLY, MANY OF THE
FATALITIES TOOK PLACE, AS JENNA
WAS SAYING EARLIER, IN A
KINDERGARTEN CLASSROOM.
JUST AN AWFUL SITUATION.
WE ARE STILL WAITING FOR A
POLICE BRIEFING.
THE NEWS CONFERENCE SET TO BEGIN
IN 15 MINUTES OR SO, BUT
OBVIOUSLY, IN A FLUID SITUATION
LIKE THIS VERY OFTEN THOSE
THINGS ARE POSTPONED.
YOU CAN SEE THE BANK OF
MICROPHONES THERE AT THE READY.
JENNA: A FLUID SITUATION, JON,
AS YOU JUST MENTIONED.
STATE AND LOCAL FIRMS ARE
INVOLVED.
WE JUST HEARD FROM JAY CARPNY
THAT THE PRESIDENT IS AWARE OF
THIS SCHOOL SHOOTING AND IS
RECEIVING REGULAR UPDATES ON IT.
WE ALSO UNDERSTAND THAT THE FBI
IS SUPPORTING STATE LAW
ENFORCEMENT AT LEAST AT THIS
TIME.
WHAT YOU'VE BEEN WATCHING ALONG
WITH US FOR THE LAST SEVERAL
HOURS HAS BEEN A VERY ORGANIZED
CHAOS, IF YOU WILL.
MANY RESPONDERS TO THE SCENE,
MULTIPLE AMBULANCES, BUT AT THE
SAME TIME WE'VE BEEN QUESTIONING
ABOUT WHAT ACTUALLY HAPPENED
WITH THE INJURIES AND
FATALITIES.
WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THAT
NOW.
AS HARRIS MENTIONED, AS JON
MENTION LD, WE'RE JUST GETTING
INITIAL REPORTS AT THIS TIME
THAT THERE ARE CHILDREN AMONG
THE DEAD TO THE LEFT OF YOUR
SCREAM, YOU SEE SOMEONE RUNNING.
GUYS, IS THAT A LIVE SHOT?
JUST TO BE CLEAR, WHAT YOU'RE
SEEING BEHIND THE SCHOOL THERE
WITH THE WOODED AREA, AS WE SAW
ONE OF THE SCENES THAT SEEMED
ACTIVE, SOME LAW ENFORCEMENT
RUSHING INTO THIS FIELD IN THE
BACK, AND WE'RE STILL TRYING TO
FIGURE OUT HOW THAT, THAT ADDS
INTO THE INVESTIGATION.
WERE THEY CONCERNED ABOUT AN
ACCOMPLICE?
IT DOESN'T SEEM TO BE THE CASE
AT THIS TIME DESPITE SOME EARLY
REPORTS.
WHAT ABOUT THE WEAPONS?
WE'RE HEARING MULTIPLE REPORTS,
ONE BEING CONFIRMED THAT THERE
WERE TWO GUNS AT THE SCENE, BUT
WHAT ABOUT OTHER FIREARMS AS
WELL?
AGAIN, A VERY DEVELOPING
SITUATION THREE HOURS IN.
WE DO KNOW THE SHOOTING TOOK
PLACE 9:40 EASTERN TIME, RIGHT
AS CLASSES GOT STARTED.
JON: THERE ALSO WERE REPORTS
THAT AUTHORITIES WERE STILL
LOOKING FOR A SECOND VEHICLE
THEY BELIEVED TO BE INVOLVED,
THEY WERE LOOKING FOR A BURR
GANDHI VAN WITH A BLOWN-OUT BACK
WINDOW.
WHETHER THERE MIGHT HAVE BEEN
ANOTHER GUNMAN INVOLVED, AGAIN,
IT SEEMED SPECULATIVE IN THE
EARLY GOING, BUT THEY ARE
APPARENTLY ACTIVELY LOOKING FOR
A SECOND VEHICLE.
HARRIS IS STILL WORKING THE
STORY FOR US FROM THE BREAKING
NEWS DESK AND PERHAPS CAN BRING
US SOME NEW INFORMATION.
HARRIS?
>> Reporter: YOU KNOW, AS THE
STORY WAS BREAKING, ONE OF THE
THINGS THAT I DO, JON ASK AND
JENNA, IS I DO JUMP ONLINE AND
TRY TO SEE WHO I MIGHT WANT TO
FOLLOW.
REPRESENTATIVE JOHN FRAY, WHO
SERVES HIS SEVENTH TERM RIGHT
NOW CONNECTICUT HOUSE OF
REPRESENTATIVES, HAS BEEN
TWEETING OUT IN THE LAST SHORT
WHILE THAT HE HAS NIECES AND
NEPHEWS AT THAT SCHOOL, THAT
THEY HAVE BEEN PULLED OUT, THAT
THEY ARE AT THE FIREHOUSE, AND
THEY ARE SAFE.
REPRESENTATIVE JOHN FRAY SAYS
THAT HE IS LEARNING THERE ON THE
GROUND AND SEEING REPORTS THAT A
GUNMAN WHO WAS MASKED CAME INTO
THE NEWTON TOWN SCHOOL.
SO THIS IS ONE OF THE AREAS THAT
WE'LL FOLLOW, THOSE LOCAL
OFFICIALS, IF YOU WILL, THOSE
ELECTED OFFICIALS WHO ARE
COMMUNICATING VIA ONLINE.
BACK TO YOU GUYS.
JON: ALL RIGHT.
HARRIS FAULKNER WORKING THE
STORY FROM OUR BREAKING NEWS
DESK.
AGAIN, WE HAVE BEEN TOLD TO
EXPECT A POLICE NEWS CONFERENCE
IN ABOUT TEN MINUTES, BUT VERY
OFTEN IN A SITUATION LIKE THIS
THOSE THINGS GET PUSHED BACK AND
BACK AND BACK.
STILL A VERY CHAOTIC SITUATION
EVEN AS RECENTLY AS, OH, HALF AN
HOUR AGO OR PERHAPS A BIT MORE
WHEN WE WERE SPEAKING TO THE
MAYOR OF DANBURY, HE SAID THAT
THE SWEEP OF THE SCHOOL WAS
STILL UNDERWAY.
POLICE GO IN IN A SITUATION LIKE
THIS, THEY HAVE TO MAKE SURE
THAT THEY HAVE COVERED EVERY
BASE AND CLEARED EVERY
CLASSROOM, SO THEY HAVE A
SIZABLE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL THAT
HOUSES NORMALLY ABOUT 600
STUDENTS TO GO THROUGH, AND THEY
WERE STILL UPSIDE WAY WITH THAT
PROJECT -- UNDERWAY WITH THAT
PROJECT WITHIN THE LAST HOUR.
SO, AGAIN, WE HAVE IT CONFIRMED
THAT THERE ARE AT LEAST FIVE
CHILDREN AND FOUR ADULTS WHO ARE
DEAD IN THIS SITUATION, BUT THE
NUMBER COULD GO HIGHER.
JENNA: WE'RE ACTUALLY HEARING
SOME CONFIRMATION THAT THE
NUMBER PROBABLY IS HIGHER AT
THIS TIME AND ALSO LEARNING A
LITTLE BIT MORE ABOUT THE
SHOOTER IN THIS SITUATION.
ACCORDING TO ONE OF OUR FOX NEWS
PRODUCERS, WE'RE NOW LEARNING
THAT THE SHOOTER WAS WEARING A
MILITARY VEST.
THERE IS A POSSIBLE SECOND
SHOOTER, BUT THAT IS NOT
CONFIRMED AT THIS TIME.
AS WE'VE MENTIONED TO YOU IN THE
REPORTS ABOUT THE SECOND SHOOTER
HAVE GONE BACK AND FORTH ALONG
WITH THE REPORT OF AN ADDITIONAL
CAR THAT LAW ENFORCEMENT MIGHT
BE LOOKING FOR.
ACCORDING TO THIS ONE REPORT
FROM OUR FOX NEWS PRODUCER AS
WELL, WE'RE HEARING THAT THERE'S
26 DEICED AT THIS TIME. --
DECEASED AT THIS TIME.
EIGHT ADULTS AND 18 CHILDREN
ACCORDING TO OUR LATEST
INFORMATION.
AT THIS TIME, AS YOU CONTINUE TO
TAKE IN VIDEO THAT WE HAVE OF
THE SCENE ALONG WITH THE LIVE
SHOT OF THE PRESS CONFERENCE
THAT IS GOING TO BE UNDERWAY IN
A MOMENT, WE CAN ALSO REPORT
THAT THERE IS NO CURRENT, ACTIVE
SHOOTER.
WE DID TELL YOU THAT THE GUNMAN,
ONE GUNMAN WAS DEAD AT THE
SCENE.
WHAT TRANSPIRED, WHETHER HE TOOK
HIS OWN LIFE OR WHETHER OR NOT
LAW ENFORCEMENT WAS INVOLVED, WE
DO NOT KNOW.
WE DO KNOW THAT POLICE HAVE
CLEARED THE SCHOOL, AND THE
GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT IS ON
THE SCENE AS WELL.
JON: WE ARE TOLD THAT THAT
NUMBER, JENNA, THE 26 DEAD
ACTUALLY DOES NOT INCLUDE THE
GUNMAN.
WE'RE TOLD THAT 18 CHILDREN ARE
DECEASED AND EIGHT, EIGHT ADULTS
WHO WERE WORKING INSIDE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, IT
CERTAINLY RANKS AS WITHIN OF THE
WORST -- ONE OF THE WORST MASS
SHOOTINGS IN THIS COUNTRY IN
DECADES REALLY.
26 DEAD SO FAR.
WHO WAS THE GUNMAN, WHAT WAS THE
MOTIVE?
WE DON'T KNOW YET.
BUT, AGAIN, THAT NUMBER COULD GO
UP.
THREE PEOPLE HAVE BEEN TAKEN TO
LOCAL HOSPITALS.
WE DON'T KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT
THEIR CONDITIONS.
AGAIN, THE FACT THAT A
RELATIVELY SMALL NUMBER OF
INJURED WERE TAKEN AWAY IS, IN
THIS SITUATION, NOT A GOOD SIGN.
JENNA: WE FELT SOME COMFORT
EARLIER ON WHEN WE WERE WATCHING
THE LIVE SCENE AT THE TRIAGE
MATS THAT WERE ON THE GROUND AND
THINKING, WELL, MAYBE IF THERE'S
NO ONE BEING TAKEN OUT OF THE
BUILDING ON A STRETCHER, MAYBE
THIS IS LIMITED IN SCOPE.
AND WHAT WE'RE LEARNING NOW IS A
VERY DIFFERENT PICTURE, INDEED.
SO AGAIN, AS WE'RE REPORTING TO
YOU, 26 DECEASED AT THIS TIME; 8
ADULTS, 18 CHILDREN.
WHERE THE SHOOTING TOOK PLACE IS
STILL UNDONE FIRMED. --
UNCONFIRMED.
WE HAVE HEARD DIFFERING REPORTS,
ONE BEING THE PRINCIPAL'S
OFFICE, ONE BEING THE
KINDERGARTEN CLASS, THE OTHER
THE FIRST GRADE.
A PARENT JOINED US A FEW MINUTES
AGO, HER THIRD GRADER WAS IN A
READING CLASS, AND HER TEACHER
TOLD THE CLASS THIS IS
CONSTRUCTION WORK, THIS IS A
HAMMER AND GOT THE STUDENTS INTO
A BATHROOM AND LOCKED THE DOORS
THERE.
THEY KEPT THAT DOOR LOCKED AND
KEPT THE STUDENTS INSIDE THE
BATHROOM UNTIL POLICE CAME AND
TOOK THEM TO THE FIREHOUSE.
THE SCENE THAT THEY DESCRIBE,
THE YOUNG STUDENT, THE
8-YEAR-OLD, SAYS SHE SAW
SHATTERED GLASS IN THE BUILDING,
SOME BLOOD AS WELL.
SHE ALSO SAW A POLICE OFFICER
CARRYING OUT WHAT LOOKED LIKE AN
INJURED LITTLE BOY.
THE STATUS OF THAT LITTLE BOY,
HIS IDENTITY WE DON'T KNOW AT
THIS TIME.
TRYING TO FIGURE THAT OUT FOR
YOU AS WELL.
JON: THE SHOOTER, WE'RE TOLD,
WAS DRESSED IN BLACK BDUs AND
A MILITARY-STYLE VEST.
IT CERTAINLY SOUNDS LIKE THE
KIND OF PREPLANNED THING THAT
YOU SAW IN THE AURORA MOVIE
SHOOTING MASSACRE.
THIS DOESN'T NECESSARILY HAVE
ALL THE HALLMARKS OF A DOMESTIC
DISPUTE THAT CAUSED SOMEBODY TO
SUDDENLY SNAP AND WALK INTO
SCHOOL, THIS SOUNDS LIKE IT WAS
PLANNED.
BUT, AGAIN CAN, YOU KNOW, ALL OF
THAT IS FOR ANOTHER DAY.
RIGHT NOW THERE IS THE GRIEVING
TO HANDLE.
EIGHTEEN STUDENTS, WE'RE TOLD,
ARE DEAD AT THIS CONNECTICUT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
EIGHT ADULTS AS WELL AT THE
HANDS OF A GUNMAN WHO TOOK AT
LEAST TWO WEAPONS, A GLOCK AND A
CIG SAUER, INTO AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, POSSIBLY EVEN A
KINDERGARTEN CLASSROOM AND
OPENED FIRE.
IT'S JUST BEYOND COMPREHENSION
HOW SOMEBODY COULD WANT TO DO
SOMETHING LIKE THIS, BUT THAT'S
WHAT THEY'RE DEALING WITH IN
CONNECTICUT RIGHT NOW.
JENNA: THE BIG QUESTION FOR ALL
THESE STORIES IS WHY, YOU KNOW,
WHAT IS THE MOTIVE, WHY WOULD
ANYONE DO THIS EVER?
WE KNOW THAT'S A QUESTION WE
STRUGGLE WITH AND YOU STRUGGLE
WITH AT HOME, AND BRIGHTLY SO.
HARRIS -- RIGHTFULLY SO.
WE SAY BDUs, THAT'S BATTLE
DRESS UNIFORMS.
THIS GUY HOWEVER OLD HE WAS WAS
DRESS INSIDE WHAT SEEMS TO BE
DESCRIBED IN MILITARY GEAR, AND
THAT DOESN'T SUGGEST IT'S
OFFICIAL MILITARY GEAR.
YOU CAN BUY THIS STUFF ONLINE,
AND, YOU KNOW --
>> Reporter: ABSOLUTELY.
YOUR CONNECTION TO THE MILITARY
AND MINE AS A DEPENDENT, I
IMMEDIATELY WANTED TO KNOW MORE
ABOUT WHAT THIS GUY MIGHT HAVE
LOOKED LIKE.
NOW, REMEMBER THE REPRESENTATIVE
THERE, FRAY, HAD TWEETED OUT GUY
SEEN MASKED GUNMAN.
MASK WE'RE NOT POSITIVE ABOUT,
BUT DRESSED IN BLACK BDU
UNIFORMS, THOSE ARE VITAL TO
EVERY MISSION.
THAT'S HOW THEY'RE TERMED IN THE
MILITARY.
THEY'RE CUTTING-EDGE MILITARY
GEAR.
THAT WOULD MEAN THIS GUY WALKS
ON THE SCENE, HE'S GOING TO BE A
TOUGH TARGET EVEN IF YOU DO HAVE
AN OPPORTUNITY TO TAKE HIM OUT
THE WAY HE'S DRESSED AND QUITE
FRIGHTENING.
CAN YOU IMAGINE THIS FOR THE
CHILDREN?
WE WANT TO BRING EVERYBODY
FORWARD NOW WITH THE STORY.
THE TIMETABLE FOR THE NEWS
CONFERENCE IS SHIFT AGO LITTLE
BIT.
WE WERE HOPING IT WAS ABOUT
THREE AND A HALF MINUTES, THEY
MAY TAKE A LITTLE MORE TIME.
WE'LL POP UP WITH IT AS SOON AS
IT HAPPENS, OF COURSE, HERE ON
FOX NEWS CHANNEL.
BUT I CAN TELL YOU FROM VERY
EARLY ON LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE
WITH THE NEWTOWN POLICE
DEPARTMENT THERE AND HIS
EMERGENCY RESPONSE TEAM WERE
WORKING FIRST TO GET THE TRIAGE
TOGETHER, THEY PULLED THAT BACK
WHEN THEY REALIZED IT WASN'T
NECESSARY AND PEELED THOSE TARPS
OFF THE GROUND ABOUT 45 MINUTES
AGO.
AND THEN THEY WERE SETTING UP
THE COMMAND CENTER ABOUT TWO
MILES FROM THIS LOCATION.
WE KNOW THAT THAT HAS BEEN THE
CENTRAL POINT.
THEY'VE NOTIFIED THE PRESIDENT
FROM THERE LETTING HIM KNOW, AND
I WOULD GUESS MANY MORE DETAILS
THAN WE WERE GIVEN VERY EARLY ON
AND EVEN NOW.
SO AS WE WAIT FOR THAT NEWS
CONFERENCE AND WE GET THOSE
HEARTBREAKING NUMBERS THAT NOW
ARE BEING CONFIRMED; 26 DEAD --
NOT INCLUDING THE GUNMAN -- 18
OF THEM CHILDREN.
NO DOUBT WE'LL LEARN MORE
POSSIBLY AS EARLY AS THE TOP OF
THE HOUR, BUT POTENTIALLY A
LITTLE BIT AFTER THAT.
JON AND JENNA?
JON: WE ARE AWAITING THIS NEWS
CONFERENCE FROM AUTHORITIES.
IT APPEARS THAT THEY ARE GETTING
READY TO BEGIN, HARRIS.
THEY ARE GIVING SOME MICROPHONE
CHECKS AND SO FORTHRIGHT NOW.
YOU CAN SEE IN THIS VIDEOTAPE
FROM EARLIER, UM, JUST THE CHAOS
THAT ERUPTED OUTSIDE THIS
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, A VERY,
VERY PEACEFUL PLACE ABOUT 60
MILES TO THE NORTH AND EAST OF
NEW YORK CITY.
NOT THE KIND OF THING WHERE YOU
EXPECT THIS TO HAPPEN ON A
BEAUTIFUL FRIDAY MORNING JUST
BEFORE CHRISTMAS AND IN THE
MIDDLE OF HANUKKAH.
BUT JUST WHAT AN AWFUL SITUATION
HAS REALLY TRANSFORMED THAT
VILLAGE, THAT TOWN AS A GUNMAN
WALKS INTO THIS ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL WITH TWO GUNS AND OPENS
FIRE.
JENNA: A TOWN LIKE SO MANY
ACROSS OUR COUNTRY, JON.
LESS THAN 30,000 PEOPLE, A
SCHOOL WITH NEARLY 700 STUDENTS,
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADE.
AGAIN, ACCORDING TO UNCONFIRMED
REPORTS, THE KUNDER GARTEN
CLASS -- KINDERGARTEN CLASS IS
POTENTIALLY WHERE THE MAIN PART
OF THE SHOOTING TOOK PLACE.
ALTHOUGH WE DO KNOW THAT 18
CHILDREN ARE INVOLVED IN THIS
SHOOTING ARE DEAD, WE DO NOT
KNOW THEIR AGES, WE DO NOT KNOW
THEIR CLASSES AS WE'VE HEARD
CONFLICTING NEWS FROM THE GROUND
THERE.
IT COULD BE A FIRST GRADE CLASS
AS WELL.
WE'VE ALSO HEARD OF MULTIPLE
DEATHS AS WELL WITH ADULTS.
SO HOPEFULLY WHEN WE GET THIS
PRESS CONFERENCE, WE'RE GOING TO
GET MORE DETAILS FOR YOU BECAUSE
THE INFORMATION COMING OUT OF
THIS BREAKING NEWS SITUATION HAS
BEEN DIFFICULT ON SO MANY LEVELS
TO PIECE TOGHE