BECAUSE DURING THE HOLIDAYS,
KEEPING YOUR IDENTITY PROTECTED
MEANS KEEPING YOUR
FAMILY PROTECTED.
>> Gretchen: COMING UP ON
TOMORROW'S SHOW, I'M NOT SURE
WHY WE NASA THERE, THERE IS SOME
UNDERPINNING STORY GOING ON.
>> Brian: BECAUSE IT'S A HOLY
MOMENT.
TIL THEE CARDINAL DOLAN WILL BE
HERE.
CARDINAL TIMOTHY DOLAN.
>> Gretchen: AND DANA PERINO
WILL BE HERE WITH HER POLITICAL
ANALYSIS AS USUAL.
>> Steve: A WORD ABOUT THE JETS?
>> Brian: THEY LOST.
IT'S OVER.
IT IS TEBOW TIME.
IF YOU HAVE TO RUN FROM THE TV,
RUN TO THE RADIO.
GRETCHEN WILL BE UP THERE IN
HALF AN HOUR.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT SHE'LL BE
WEARING.
>> Steve: PROBABLY SOMETHING
LIKE THAT.
SEE YOU TOMORROW.
BILL: IS THERE A DEAL.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
GOOD MORNING, EVERYBODY.
FOX NEWS ALERT.
REPORTS OF PROGRESS TO AVOID
THE FISCAL CLIFF WHERE THAT
CALENDAR IS MOVING TOWARD
IT.
BOTH SIDES SAID TO BE GIVING
SOME GROUND.
ONLY DAYS BEFORE MASSIVE TAX
HIKES HIT EVERY SINGLE
AMERICAN.
WE SAY GOOD MORNING.
LIVE IN NEW YORK.
I'LL BILL HEMMER.
WELL COME HERE.
ANYTIME WE TALK ABOUT THE
FISCAL CLIFF GOOD DAY FOR
ME.
NICE TO SEE YOU, MARTHA.
MARTHA: SOMEWHAT OF A
RELIEF.
YOU KNOW, WELCOME BACK.
BILL: THANK YOU.
MARTHA: TOUGH FEW DAYS UP
THERE FOR YOU AND FOR
EVERYBODY ELSE.
WE'RE GOING TO GET TO A
LITTLE BIT MORE OF THAT IN A
LITTLE WHILE BUT FOR NOW WE
WANT TO FOCUS OWN THE
SPEAKER OF THE HOUSE, THAT
MAN, JOHN BOEHNER, TRYING TO
WORK OUT A DEAL WITH
PRESIDENT OBAMA AS THEY
DISCUSSED PRESIDENT'S LATEST
OFFER.
CALLS FOR RAISING 1.2
TRILLION IS THE NUMBER BEING
RAISED BY REVENUE, TAXES,
BASICALLY OVER THE NEXT 10
YEARS.
IT KEEPS IN PLACE THE
BUSH-ERA TAX CUTS FOR ANYONE
MAKING LESS, THIS IS THE NEW
MAGIC NUMBER ON THIS.
IT WAS 250 AS YOU REMEMBER.
NOW THEY'RE AT 400,000.
SOME PEOPLE THINK IT SHOULD
BE A MILLION DOLLARS.
LOTS OF NEGOTIATING STILL TO
COME.
BILL: WE'RE TOLD THAT IS A
BIG CONCESSION.
SOURCES TELL US SIGNIFICANT
ISSUES REMAIN ON THE TABLE.
THEY ARE WORKING ON FINER
DETAILS.
STUART VARNEY WITH ANALYSIS.
FIRST, CHIEF POLITICAL
CORRESPONDENT CARL CAMERON
IS LIVE ON THE HILL.
WE'LL SEE IF BOEHNER IS BOB
BARKER HERE IN THE END.
WHAT IS THE LATEST, CARL?
>> Reporter: HEY,.
BILL:.
CRUNCH TIME AT THE CAPITOL
AND THE FISCAL CLIFF AND HOW
TO AVERT IT.
THERE WAS A OFFER FROM THE
PRESIDENT THAT SIGNALS
MR. OBAMA IS PREPARED TO
GIVE A LITTLE BIT ON HIS
INSISTENCE RAISING TAXES ON
WEALTHY AMERICANS.
THAT JUMPED FROM INCOMES OF
250,000 AND ABOVE TO 400.
DEMOCRATS SAY A BIG, BIG
MOVE BY THE PRESIDENT.
WHETHER OR NOT THAT WILL
ACTUALLY GO OVER WITH
REPUBLICANS PARTICULARLY IN
THE HOUSE IS VERY, VERY OPEN
QUESTION.
THEY'RE MEETING AS WE SPEAK
OVER ON THE HOUSE SIDE.
MR. BOEHNER AND HIS
LEADERSHIP TEAM ARE GOING TO
GO OVER THE DETAILS OF THIS
LATEST OFFER FROM THE
ADMINISTRATION WITH
RANK-AND-FILE HOUSE
REPUBLICANS.
THE UNIFIED REPUBLICAN
LEADERSHIP IS KEY HERE.
THUS FAR BOEHNER HAD THE GOP
PRETTY MUCH BEHIND HIM.
THE SPEAKER, HIS MAJORITY
LEADER ERIC CANTOR, HIS WHIP,
KEVIN McCARTHY AND BUDGET
CHAIRMAN PAUL RYAN HAVE BEEN
VERY, VERY STRONGLY LOCKED
IN ARMS AS THEY'RE
NEGOTIATING WITH THE
PRESIDENT GIVING BOEHNER AN
OPPORTUNITY TO GO DOWN THERE
AND SAYING WHAT COULD BE A
FEASIBLE DEAL OR NOT.
THERE IS LOT OF SKEPTICISM
AMONG THOSE LEADERS ABOUT
THIS PROPOSAL FROM THE
PRESIDENT.
THEY SAY THE TAX RELIEF IS
TOO MUCH.
STILL TOO HIGH AT $1.2
TRILLION AND THAT THE
PRESIDENT'S SPENDING
REDUCTIONS AREN'T BALANCED.
THEY INSIST MR. BOEHNER AND
THE REPUBLICANS HAVE PUT THE
POSSIBILITY OF TAX INCREASES
AND LETTING BUSH TAX CUTS
EXPIRE FOR THE WEALTHIEST ON
THE TABLE BUT THEIR
THRESHOLD IS A MILLION
DOLLARS OF INCOME AND
HIGHER.
BY PUTTING IT ON THE TABLE
THEY SAY THE PRESIDENT HAS
TO COME UP WITH SIGNIFICANT
SPENDING REDUCTIONS AND THEY
ARGUE THAT HAS YET TO
APPEAR.
WHEN THEY COME OUT OF THE
MEETING AT 9:00 REPUBLICANS
WILL HAVE A LOT MORE TO SAY.
THEY BELIEVE THERE IS
POTENTIAL FOR PROGRESS BUT
NO DEAL YET.
BILL: TWO YEARS AGO THEY
THOUGHT THEY HAD A DEAL AND
THREW HIM OUT THE DOOR.
12, 13 DAYS AGO, WHAT WOULD
BE THE TIMETABLE THEN, CARL?
>> Reporter: VIRTUALLY
PASSED AS WE SPEAK.
BECAUSE OF THE CHRISTMAS
HOLIDAY THE LIKELIHOOD OF
THE HOUSE REPUBLICANS
GETTING ANY SORT OF A
MIRACLE DEAL TOGETHER THAT
COULD PASS MUSTER WITH THE
WHITE HOUSE AND DEMOCRATS IS
SMALL.
IF THAT MIRACLE WERE TO
HAPPEN, IT IS LESS LIKELY
THE SENATE COULD COME BACK
AFTER CHRISTMAS AND GET
ANYTHING DONE BEFORE NEW
YEAR'S.
THERE HAS BEEN A LOSS HERE
IN THE SENATE.
THE SENATOR FROM THE HAWAII,
DANIEL INOUYE AT 88 YEARS
OLD PASSED AWAY YESTERDAY.
THAT WILL LIKELY CAUSE
INTERRUPTION FOR A FEW DAYS
FOR MEMORIAL SERVICES NEXT
COUPLE WEEKS.
WHETHER FOR THE PRESIDENT
AND MOST MEMBERS OF CONGRESS
TO GO TO HAWAII OR FOR THE
LATE SENATOR TO LIE IN STATE
AT THE CAPITOL, ALL THINGS
WOULD CUT UP MORE TIME,
MEANING IN ALL LIKELIHOOD,
IF THEY FIND AN AGREEMENT
THAT COULD BE CONSIDERED
REAL THEY WOULD HAVE TO GIVE
THEMSELVES A LITTLE BIT OF
OVERTIME AND PASS ONE OF THE
LEGISLATIVE VEHICLES THAT
ESSENTIALLY STOPS THE CLOCK
TO TAKE IT INTO NEW YEAR'S.
THAT WAS NOT THE PLAN.
THAT IS WHY THEY PUT
TOGETHER WHAT WAS CALLED
SEQUESTER SO THEY WOULD BE
FORCED TO PUT A LEGISLATIVE
GUN TO THEIR HEADS TO MAKE A
DEAL.
LOOKS LIKE THEY MAY GIVE
THEMSELVES A LITTLE BIT OF
AFTER SCHOOL STUDY TIME.
BILL: WE'LL SEE HOW THAT
PAYS OFF.
CARL CAMERON LEADING OUR
COVERAGE.
THANK YOU, SIR.
MARTHA: THE BOTTOM LINE
REALLY DOES THIS DEAL BEGIN
TO ADDRESS THE ECONOMIC
PROBLEMS THAT EXIST IN THIS
COUNTRY?
STUART VARNEY, THE ANCHOR OF
"VARNEY & COMPANY" ON THE
FOX BUSINESS NETWORK, HAS
BEEN THINKING ABOUT THIS
MORNING AND FOR MANY DAYS IN
FACT.
STUART, WHAT DO YOU THINK
ABOUT THIS DEAL, DOES IT
HELP?
>> OKAY, IF YOU LOOK AT THIS
PURELY ECONOMICALLY, THEN
THIS FRAMEWORK OF A DEAL
DOES NOT ADDRESS AMERICA'S
TWO MAJOR ECONOMIC PROBLEMS.
THAT WOULD BE GROWTH AND
ALSO THE DEBT.
JUST LOOK AT THE SPENDING
SIDE OF THE FRAMEWORK FOR
THIS DEAL.
THE PRESIDENT IS NOT
OFFERING ANY SIGNIFICANT CUT
IN SOCIAL SECURITY BENEFITS
IN THE FUTURE.
IT'S A TINY CUT.
IF YOU LOOK AT MEDICARE, THE
PRESIDENT WANTS TO KEEP THE
AGE OF ELIGIBILITY AT 65.
NO SAVINGS THERE BY GOING TO
67.
THE PRESIDENT WANTS A
TWO-YEAR DEBT LIMIT DEBATE.
ACTUALLY HE WANTS A TWO YEAR
PERIOD, IN WHICH HE CAN
SPEND MONEY FREELY, A BLANK
CHECK FOR SPENDING BECAUSE
THERE WILL BE NO DEBT
CEILING DEBATE FOR TWO
YEARS.
HE ALSO WANTS $50 BILLION
WORTH OF NEW SPENDING ON
INFRASTRUCTURE.
YOU ADD ALL OF THAT LOT UP
TOGETHER, WHAT YOU'RE
LOOKING AT IS A TRILLION
DOLLAR DEFICIT FOR THE NEXT
FOUR YEARS EACH AND EVERY
YEAR.
YOU'RE ALSO LOOKING, IF YOU
COUPLE IT WITH TAX HIKES
THERE IS ALSO IN THAT
FRAMEWORK, YOU'RE LOOKING AT
A GROWTH RATE OF MAYBE 2 OR
3% FOR THE ECONOMY AT BEST.
NOT THE 4, 5, 6% WE WANT.
DIRECTLY TO ANSWER YOUR
QUESTION, MARTHA, THIS
FRAMEWORK DOES NOT ANSWER
AMERICA'S PRINCIPLE ECONOMIC
PROBLEMS OF THE DAY.
MARTHA: FOR THOSE WHO ARE
WORRIED WE ARE SLIPPING
CLOSER TO BECOMING A
GREASE-LIKE SITUATION.
IT SOUND AS IF YOU'RE SAYING
THIS IS NO REMEDY FOR THAT,
THIS IS A BANDAID AT BEST?
>> NO, IT IS NOT.
YOU'RE GUARANTEED MUCH
HIGHER DEFICITS CONTINUING
INTO THE FUTURE, AT LEAST A
TRILLION DOLLARS A YEAR.
GREECE HAS A DEBT PROBLEM.
WE HAVE A SIGNIFICANT DEBT
PROBLEM.
MARTHA: INDEED.
STUART, THANK YOU.
>> SURE.
BILL: $16 TRILLION.
NOW TO NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
ATTEMPTED NORMALCY AND SO
MUCH HEARTACHE.
SCHOOLS IN THE AREA OPENING
FIRST TIME SINCE FRIDAY'S
MASSACRE EXCEPT OF COURSE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY WHICH
REMAINS CLOSED INDEFINITELY
AS POLICE CONTINUE THEIR
INVESTIGATION THERE.
THERE ARE QUESTIONS WHETHER
IT WILL BE EVER REOPEN.
VOLUNTEERS IN THE
NEIGHBORING TOWN OF MONROE,
SEVEN MILES AWAY, HARD AT
WORK, GETTING A FORMER
MIDDLE SCHOOL READY FOR
SANDY HOOK STUDENTS.
ALL OF THIS AS THE GRIM TASK
OF BEARING SO MANY YOUNG
INNOCENTS GETS UNDERWAY.
10:00 IN THE MORNING FUNERAL
SERVICES BEGIN FOR JAMES
MATTIOLI.
FOLLOWED BY SERVICES FOR
JESSICA REEK COAST.
-- REKOS.
A RABBI SPOKE ABOUT THAT
SERVICE.
>> BEING CELEBRATED AS A
PURE INNOCENT CHILD BY THE
PROMISE OF LIFE AHEAD OF
HIM.
WHO BROUGHT JOY TO HIS
FAMILY AND TO HIS COMMUNITY
AND WHO WILL BE SORELY
MISSED.
AS HIS OLDER BROTHER SAID HE
COULD HAVE BEEN ANYTHING IF
HE HAD GROWN UP.
THIS IS TRAGEDY THAT WE HAVE
NO ANSWERS FOR THIS.
BILL: RICK LEVENTHAL LIVE IN
NEW TOWN WITH THIS NOW.
DO WE KNOW ANYMORE DETAILS
ABOUT THE KILLER, RICK?
>> Reporter: WELL, BILL, WE
HAVE LEARNED NEW THINGS
ABOUT ADAM LANZA.
PARTICULARLY HE TRIED
DESPERATELY TO COVER HIS
TRACKS BEFORE HIS MURDEROUS
RAMPAGE, SMASHING THE
COMPUTER HARD DRIVE
ACCORDING TO POLICE SOURCES
MAKING IT MUCH MORE
DIFFICULT TO READ HIS
ELECTRONIC DATA TRAIL HE
LEFT BEHIND A FORMER
BABY-SITTER WAS SAYING THERE
WERE EARLY SIGNS OF HIS
UNPREDICTABLE BEHAVIOR.
ADAM'S MOTHER WARNED TO KEEP
CLOSE EYE ON THE 12-YEAR-OLD
BOY AT ALL TIMES.
NEVER TURN HIS BACK ON ADAM
OR GO TO THE BATHROOM.
LESS THAN A WEEK BEFORE
FRIDAY'S SHOOTING, NANCY
LANZA, ADAM'S MOTHER THAT
SHE WAS LOSING ADAM AND HE
WAS GETTING WORSE.
HE SUFFERED FROM ASPERGER'S
A FORM OF AUTISM AND HE
APPARENTLY USED TO BURN
HIMSELF BECAUSE HE FELT NO
PAIN.
HE SPENT MOST OF THE TIME
ALONE IN THE TWO BEDROOMS
THAT HE HAD IN THE FAMILY'S
SPRAWLING HOME AND READING
AND PLAYING COMPUTER GAMES.
POLICE TRYING TO LEARN ALL
THEY CAN ABOUT ADAM LANZA IN
THE DAYS AHEAD, BILL.
BILL: TWO FUNERALS
YESTERDAY.
WE MENTIONED MORE TODAY,
RICK.
>> Reporter: YEAH.
AND GOVERNOR DAN MALLOY
ATTENDED ONE OF THOSE
FUNERALS FOR THE TWO
6-YEAR-OLD BOYS LAID TO REST
YESTERDAY.
HE TALKED ABOUT HOW
DIFFICULT IT WAS TO FIND
WORDS AT THE FUNERAL.
HOW YOU TRY TO FEEL THEIR
PAIN BUT YOU CAN'T.
HOW HEARTBREAKING IT WAS TO
SEE THAT LITTLE COFFIN.
IT WAS JACK PINTO AND NOAH
POZNER BURIED YESTERDAY.
TWO MORE FUNERALS TODAY, FOR
JESSICA REKOS, A 6-YEAR-OLD
WHO LOVED HORSES AND JAMES
MATIOLI, WHO DESCRIBED BY
FAMILY AS A NUMBERS GUY.
THEY WILL BE EULOGIZED IN
SANDY HOOK.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
REMAINS A CRIME SCENE.
NO WORD IF OR WHEN IT WILL
EVER REOPEN.
YESTERDAY MOVING VANS ROLLED
UP TO THE DOORS HAULING OFF
ALL THE DESKS AND CHAIRS,
SUPPLY, MOVING THEM TO
FORMER CHALK HILL MIDDLE
SCHOOL IN MONROE SEVEN MILES
AWAY.
SANDY HOOK SURVIVORS WILL
ATTEND THE NEWLY RENOVATED
CHALK HILL SCHOOL SOMETIME
LATER THIS WEEK.
BILL, THE REST OF THE
SCHOOLS IN NEWTOWN ARE
OPENING TODAY.
WE HAVE SEEN A COUPLE OF
SCHOOL BUSES ROLL BY, A
SMALL SIGN OF NORMALCY
RETURNING TO THIS BEAUTIFUL
COMMUNITY.
BILL: YOU MENTIONED ANXIETY
OF THE PARENTS EVEN ON THIS
DAY.
RICK LEVENTHAL BACK LIVE IN
NEWTOWN.
MARTHA: THE TRAGEDY AT SANDY
HOOK IS RENEWING CALLS TO
TOUGHEN AMERICA'S GUN LAWS
EVEN FROM SOME DEMOCRATS WHO
HAVE STRONG RATINGS FROM THE
NRA.
VIRGINIA SENATOR JOE MANCHIN
RECALLING WHAT HAPPENED IN
CONNECTICUT AND CALLING IT A
TIPPINGPOINT.
>> IT'S TIME TO MOVE BEYOND
RHETORIC.
WE NEED TO SIT DOWN WITH A
COMMON SENSE DISCUSSION AND
MOVE IN A REASONABLE WAY AND
WHOLEHEARTEDLY TO GIVE
PEOPLE SAFE PLACE IN LIFE,
THINKING A SCHOOL MIGHT BE
ONLY SAFE HAVEN A CHILD HAD,
AND NOW THAT HAS BEEN TAKEN
AWAY.
I THINK, I LISTEN TO ALL OF
YOU SPEAKING THIS MORNING.
MIKE, I THINK YOU'RE RIGHT
ON, THIS CHANGED THE
DIALOGUE.
IT SHOULD MOVE BEYOND
WE NEED ACTION.
MARTHA: A LOT OF
CONVERSATIONS ALONG THOSE
LINES IN THE LAST COUPLE
DAYS.
AT A VIGIL IN WASHINGTON FOR
THE VICTIMS AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY, CONNECTICUT
CONGRESSWOMAN AND DEMOCRAT
ROSA DELORA, SAY REASONABLE
PEOPLE NEED TO COME TOGETHER
TO FIND SCREENABLE WAYS TO
PREVENT GUN VIOLENCE.
HERE SHE IS.
>> WE WHO SERVE IN THIS
INSTITUTION NEED TO TAKE
STEPS THAT ARE GOING TO
INSURE THAT THESE TRAGEDIES
WILL NOT HAPPEN AGAIN.
LIKE INSURING BETTER ACCESS
TO QUALITY MENTAL HEALTH
CARE, AND YES, I BELIEF IN
STRENGTHENING OUR GUN
CONTROL LAWS.
MARTHA: DEMOCRAT FRANK
LAUTENBERG AND DIANNE
FEINSTEIN SAYING IN THE NEXT
CONGRESS THEY WILL
REINTRODUCE THE BANS ON
ASSAULT WEAPONS AND HIGH
CAPACITY MAGAZINES.
LOTS MORE TO BE SAID ABOUT
ALL OF THAT.
BILL: TALK OF RENEWING GUN
CONTROL DEBATE SENDS SALE OF
FIREARMS SOARING.
GUN STORE OWNERS SAID THEY
SEE INCREASED SALE FOR
AMMUNITION WHICH IS SOME SAY
IS EASIER TO BAN THAN THE
WEAPONS THEMSELVES.
SOME STORES REPORTING
BUSIEST DAYS THEY HAVE SEEN
IN YEARS.
>> BIG-TIME, FRIDAY AND
SATURDAY ESPECIALLY THE
PLACE WAS JUST WALL-TO-WALL.
THEY'RE GOING TO DO
SOMETHING.
THAT'S OBVIOUS.
AND PEOPLE WANT TO GET STUFF
BEFORE A BAN ON WHATEVER
COMES IN.
PROBABLY MAGAZINES.
PEOPLE GET SCARED.
IT HAPPENS EVERY TIME.
>> WE HAVE 40 MILLION
REGULATIONS, YOU KNOW, JUST
LIKE THEY HAD IN PROHIBITION.
OBVIOUSLY PROHIBITION DIDN'T
WORK.
BILL: WITH STATES PERFORMING
SO MANY BACKGROUND CHECKS
WAIT TIMES USUALLY MINUTES,
JUMPED TO 12 HOURS IN SOME
CASES.
COMING UP WE'LL TALK ABOUT
IT WITH THE FORMER HOMELAND
SECURITY SECRETARY, TOM
RIDGE.
HE IS OUR GUEST COMING UP.
THE TOPIC OF MENTAL ILLNESS
AS FORMER GOVERNOR.
HE HAS A LOT OF EXPERIENCE
AT THIS.
THAT IS 9:30 A.M. EASTERN
TIME.
WHAT I WANT YOU TO
UNDERSTAND, OUR AUDIENCE TO
UNDERSTAND, HOW MUCH SADNESS
THERE IS IN THAT THE TOWN
AND HOW MUCH THEY'RE TRYING
TO MOVE FORWARD.
THIS WILL BE A VERY
DIFFICULT PROCESS AND TAKE A
VERY, VERY LONG TIME.
NONE OF US HAS EVER SEEN
ANYTHING LIKE THIS BEFORE.
MARTHA: THINK ABOUT KIDS
GETTING BACK ON SCHOOL BUSES
THIS MORNING.
AS A PARENT, IT WOULD FEEL
THAT IS WHAT THEY NEED TO
DO.
GET BACK INTO THE ROUTINE
AND GET MOVING WITH LIFE IN
SOME WAY TO RESTORE A LITTLE
BIT OF NORMALCY.
AS YOU POINT OUT, BILL, FROM
FIRST-HAND EXPERIENCE, SO,
SO POTENT.
BILL: WE'RE JUST GETTING
STARTED HERE.
AN INDEPENDENT REPORT
FINISHED WHAT REALLY
HAPPENED IN BENGHAZI.
STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICIALS
WILL TESTIFY LATER THIS
WEEK.
IN A MOMENT WE TALK TO JOHN
BOLTON ABOUT WHAT IS IN THAT
REPORT, MARTHA?
MARTHA: BREAKING NEWS THIS
MORNING.
AN AMERICAN JOURNALIST
RELEASED AFTER FIVE DAYS IN
CAPTIVITY IN SYRIA.
WE'VE GOT BRAND NEW DETAILS
ON THAT.
>> THE LAST FIVE DAYS WERE
VERY DIFFICULT.
WE'RE VERY HAPPY TO BE OUT.
WE'RE VERY HAPPY TO BE BACK
IN TURKEY.
WE LOVE BEING HERE.
WE LOVE THIS COUNTRY.
WE APPRECIATE ALL THE HELP.
THE LAST FIVE DAYS, SOME
DAYS WE WOULD RATHER FORGET
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THE WAY IT MOVES.
THE WAY IT CLEANS.
EVERYTHING ABOUT
THE ORAL-B POWER BRUSH
IS SIMPLY REVOLUTIONARY.
ORAL-B POWER BRUSHES OSCILLATE,
ROTATE
AND EVEN PULSATE
TO GENTLY LOOSEN AND BREAK UP
THAT STICKY PLAQUE
WITH MORE BRUSH MOVEMENTS
THAN MANUAL BRUSHES
AND EVEN
UP TO 50% MORE
THAN LEADING
SONIC TECHNOLOGY BRUSHES
FOR A SUPERIOR CLEAN.
ORAL-B POWER BRUSHES.
GO TO ORALB.COM
FOR THE LATEST OFFERS.
BILL: HERE WE GO, NOW.
THE FIRST OFFICIAL REVIEW OF
THE TERRORIST ATTACK IN
BENGHAZI, LIBYA, SAID TO BE
COMPLETE.
THIS COMES DAYS BEFORE THE
HEARINGS BEGAN ON CAPITOL
HILL.
HILLARY CLINTON WILL NOT
TESTIFY FOR NOW.ECOVERING FROM
THAT CONCUSSION.
JOHN BOLTON, FORMER U.S.
AMBASSADOR TO THE U.N. AND
FOX NEWS CONTRIBUTOR AND
GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
>> GOOD MORNING.
BILL: TELL ME ABOUT THIS
REVIEW BOARD, WHAT DO THEY
DO, WHO IS A PART OF THIS?
>> IT WAS APPOINTED BY THE
STATE DEPARTMENT ITSELF TO
LOOK INTO THE INCIDENT AT
BENGHAZI.
THIS IS A STANDARD
PROCEDURE.
I'M SURE THEY HAVE WRITTEN A
THOROUGH REPORT BUT IT WILL
NOT BE THE END OF THE
CONTROVERSY.
BILL: WHY WOULD IT NOT BE IF
IT IS A THOROUGH REPORT.
>> THE PEOPLE DID THE
APPOINTING ARE THE PEOPLE
WHO DID THE QUESTIONS.
I DON'T THINK THE
CONCLUSIONS WILL NECESSARILY
WITHSTAND SCRUTINY.
THEY COULD COVER THREE MAIN
AREAS.
ONE, WHY DID THE STATED
DEPARTMENT REJECT CONTINUED
REQUESTS FOR ENHANCED
SECURITY FOR BEFORE
SEPTEMBER THE 11th?
NUMBER TWO, COULD WE HAVE
DONE MORE TO PROTECT OUR
PEOPLE DURING THE ATTACK.
AND NUMB 3, WHO CAME UP WITH
THIS RIDICULOUS STORY THAT
THE WHOLE THING WAS PROVOKED
BY THE MOHAMMED VIDEO.
BILL: YOU THINK YOU GET
ANSWERS TO ALL THREE IN A
REVIEW LIKE THIS.
>> YOU HAVE THE CAPABILITY
OF IT, I DO?
>> THIS IS NOT JUST FORMER
STATE DEPARTMENT PEOPLE.
ADMIRAL MULLEN, FORMER JOINT
CHIEFS OF STAFF.
A MEMBER OF THE INTELLIGENCE
COMMUNITY IS MEMBER OF THIS
BOARD.
THEY COULD REACH OUT BEYOND
THE STATE DEPARTMENT AND I
HOPE THEY DID BUT WE
OBVIOUSLY DON'T KNOW AT THIS
POINT.
BILL: WE WILL GET SOME WORD
ON THE REPORT AND THEN IT
GOES UP TO CAPITOL HILL,
RIGHT.
THEY CAN'T KEEP A SECRET?
>> THERE ARE TWO PARTS.
CLASSIFIED VERSION AND
UNCLASSIFIEDERS HAVE.
WE'LL SEE THE UNCLASSIFIED
VERSION IN THE HEARING ON
THURSDAY AS YOU MENTIONED IS
A OPPORTUNITY FOR CONGRESS
TO ASK ABOUT IT.
BILL: DO YOU THINK THAT IS
MUST-SEE TV ON THURSDAY?
>> I'M CERTAINLY GOING TO
WATCH IT.
I'M VERY DISAPPOINTED
SECRETARY CLINTON IS NOT
THERE.
OBVIOUSLY WE WISH HER WELL
FOR THE HOLT SITUATION.
IT IS POSTPONING THE MOMENT
WHEN SHE WILL HAVE TO
TESTIFY.
BILL: SHE IS GOING TO
TESTIFY ACCORDING TO THE
REPORTS WE'RE GETTING, NOT
THIS MONTH BUT PERHAPS
JANUARY AFTER THE NEW YEAR.
>> I THINK SHE WAITED
SUCCESSFULLY TWO MONTHS
UNTIL THE ADMINISTRATIVE
REVIEW BOARD IS OUT.
THAT WAY SHE CAN READ THE
REPORT AND TAILOR THE
TESTIMONY ACCORDINGLY NOT
RISK CONTRADICTING HERSELF.
BILL: REALLY?
LET ALL THE INFORMATION GET
OUT THERE AND REACT AND
RESPOND.
>> I THINK THE SECRETARY
SHOULD HAVE BEEN ON THE HILL
RIGHT AFTER THE 9/11 AT TOCK
TO EXPLAIN TO CONGRESS WHAT
HAPPENED.
SHE MISSED TWO CRITICAL
POINTS.
SHE WILL MISS THE HEARING ON
THURSDAY AND MISSED THE
FAMOUS SUNDAY MORNING TALK
SHOWS FIVE DAYS AFTER THAT.
BILL: ARE YOU SUGGESTING SHE
IS NOT TRYING TO BE TRIPPED
UP ON THIS OR WANTS TO HAVE
ALL THE FACT AS THEY
UNDERSTAND IT NOW OR SHE IS
TRYING TO GO AROUND SOME OF
THE FACT?
>> I THINK SHE TRIED TO
AVOID SPEAKING IN PUBLIC.
I THINK THESE WITNESSES ON
THURSDAY SHOULD BE ASKED WHY
THE SECRETARY DIDN'T
TESTIFY?
WHY IS THE PRESIDENT SAID
SUSAN RICE WHO HAD NOTHING
TO DO WITH BENGHAZI WAS THE
DESIGNATED HITTER?
WHY DIDN'T ONE OF SECRETARY
CLINTON'S TWO DEPUTIES
TESTIFY?
THEY WILL BE UP THERE
THURSDAY.
THEY'RE CERTAINLY COMPETENT
PEOPLE.
WHY DIDN'T THEY TESTIFY?
BILL: THINGS TO WATCH.
TWO THINGS.
WE'LL HAVE THE REPORT THAT
LEAKS OUT, BECAUSE IT IS
UNCLASSIFIED, PARTS OF IT
AND THE HEARING LATER THIS
WEEK.
THIS STORY IS NOT OVER YET?
>> NOT BY A LONGSHOT.
BILL: WE'LL SEE WHERE IT
GOES AFTER THAT.
THANK YOU, MR. AMOUNT
AMBASSADOR, JOHN BOLTON.
MARTHA.
MARTHA: WE'RE GETTING NEW
DETAILS ON A VETERAN
AMERICAN CORRESPONDENT HELD
HOSTAGE LAST FIVE DAYS IN
SYRIA.
HE IS NOW FREE THANKFULLY.
HE IS STARTING TO SPEAK OUT
WHAT HAPPENED TO HIM.
BILL: GOOD NEWS, TODAY, HUH,
FOR A CHANGE.
THE NATION GRIEVES THE SANDY
HOOK VICTIMS WE'LL DEBATE
HOW OUR COUNTRY DEALS WITH
MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES.
WE'LL TALK WITH FORMER
PENNSYLVANIA GOVERNOR TOM
RIDGE WHO IS WITH US THIS
MORNING ON THAT.
♪ THE WEATHER OUTSIDE
IS FRIGHTFUL ♪
♪ BUT THE FIRE IS
SO DELIGHTFUL ♪
NOTHING MELTS AWAY THE COLD
LIKE A HOT, DELICIOUS BOWL
OF CHICKEN NOODLE SOUP
FROM CAMPBELL'S.
♪ LET IT SNOW, LET IT SNOW
BILL: GETTING BREAKING NEWS
FROM THE HILL NOW.
WE MENTIONED THIS TO
CARL CAMERON A FEW MOMENTS
AGO.
JOHN BOEHNER APPARENTLY IS
PLANNING TO OFFER A PLAN B
ON THE FLOOR OF THE HOUSE IN
CASE THE CLIFF CAN IN THE --
NOT BE AVOIDED.
NEGOTIATIONS CONTINUE.
WE'RE GETTING THIS FROM THE
FOLKS ON THE HILL.
WE'LL GET MORE IN A MOMENT.
A SATELLITE LAUNCHED ONLY
DAYS AGO BY NORTH KOREA
APPEARS TO BE DEAD.
IT COULD TUMBLE AROUND IN
ORBIT POSSIBLY FOR YEARS.
IT WAS RELEASED IN
CONTROVERSIAL ROCKET LAUNCH
AS A TEST FOR LONG-RANGE
MISSILE TECHNOLOGY.
NORTH KOREA CLAIMS THE
SATELLITE, WELL IT IS STILL
WORKING THEY SAY BUT U.S.
MONITORS SAY IT IS NO LONGER
BROADCASTING ANY TYPE OF
SIGNAL.
MARTHA: FOX NEWS ALERT OUT
OF SYRIA THIS MORNING WHERE
NBC IS ANNOUNCING THAT
FOREIGN CORRESPONDENT
RICHARD ENGEL AND HIS
PRODUCTION TEAM ARE NOW FEE
AND UNHURT AFTER GETTING
CAPTURED THERE LAST
THURSDAY.
IT COMES AS OPPONENTS OF
PRESIDENT ASSAD LAUNCH A NEW
OFFENSIVE NEAR THE CAPITAL
OF DAMASCUS.
LELAND VITTERT JOINS ME LIVE
IN JERUSALEM.
LELAND, AN INCREDIBLY
DRAMATIC STORY HOW THEY
GAINED THEIR FREEDOM.
>> Reporter: NO QUESTION
ABOUT IT.
THESE GUYS WERE HELD FOR
FIVE DAYS OF THE MOVED FROM
SAFE HOUSE TO SAFE HOUSE BY
PRO-ASSAD GUNMEN.
THAT'S WHEN THE PRO-ASSAD
GUNMEN WHO HAD THE NBC CREW
IN THE BACK OF A MINIVAN, IF
YOU WILL, WERE DRIVING DOWN
THE ROAD, GOT TO REBEL CHECK
POINT THERE WAS A FIREFIGHT
ENSUED AND THAT'S WHEN
RICHARD ENGEL AND HIS CREW
ESCAPED OUT OF THE VAN.
SAID LITERALLY HELP US,
WE'RE AMERICAN JOURNALISTS
GET US TO SAFETY.
THE REBELS INVOLVED DID JUST
THAT.
IT WAS ON A ROAD SIMILAR TO
THAT ENGEL AND HIS CREW WERE
TAKEN BY GUNPOINT WHAT THEY
PRESUME TO BE PRO-GOVERNMENT,
PRO-PRESIDENT ASSAD FORCES,
SHIITE MILITIA MEMBERS
HOLDING THEM.
DURING THE TIME THEY WERE
BEING HELD THEY WERE TOLD IT
WAS VERY AWFUL SITUATION.
THEY ENDURED MOCKS
EXECUTIONS.
A NUMBER OF THREATS WHAT
WOULD HAPPEN TO THE MEN.
MARTHA, THIS ISN'T -- IS THE
BEST WAY THIS STORY COULD
END.
ONE AMERICAN STILL MISSING
IN THAT COUNTRY.
MARTHA: EVERYBODY IS VERY
THANKFUL THIS DELLED THE WAY
IT DID, LELAND T SAID A LOT
WHAT IS CHANGING ON THE
GROUND IN SYRIA.
THEY BELIEVED THEY WERE
TRAVELING IN REBEL-HELD
TERRITORY BUT OBVIOUSLY THEY
WERE NOT.
WHAT IS THE LATEST THERE?
>> Reporter: WELL, THIS IS
AN INSURGENCY CIVIL WAR.
NOT ONLY DO YOU HAVE THE
ARMY FIGHTING.
YOU HAVE ALL THE PRO-ASSAD
MILITIAS AND YOU HAVE THE
REBELS.
IT APPEARS THE MOMENTUM HAS
CHANGED.
IT USED TO BE THE GOVERNMENT
IS HUNTING REBELS.
REBELS BETTER ARMED AND
BETTER TRAINED ARE HUNTING
THE GOVERNMENT BUT STILL
THESE REBELS HAVE NOT BEEN
ABLE TO CONTROL MAJOR
CITIES.
THEY HAVEN'T TAKEN ALEPPO.
CERTAINLY HAVE NOT TAKEN THE
CAPITAL DAMASCUS.
AS THINGS ON THE GROUND ARE
SHIFTING WE'RE GETTING MORE
AND MORE INDICATIONS, RUSSIA,
SYRIA'S KEY ALLY ARE GETTING
NERVOUS.
THEY MOVED WARSHIPS IN THE
MEDITERRANEAN TO CONCEIVABLY
EVACUATE RUSSIAN CITIZENS
INTO SYRIA IN THINGS
CONTINUE TO DETERIORATE.
THERE IS QUESTION OF
CHEMICAL WEAPONS.
WILL ASSAD USE HIS CHEMICAL
WEAPONS IN A LAST ACT OF
DESPERATION?
OR WILL THE REBELS SEIZE
CONTROL.
YOU HAVE A LOT OF CHEMICAL
WEAPONS IN THE HANDS OF MANY
WITHOUT COMMAND-AND-CONTROL
STRUCTURES.
MARTHA: MUCH OF THE CHAOS IN
SYRIA BUT A LITTLE BIT OF
ORDER FOR RICH AROUND ENGEL
AND HIS CREW.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
BILL:.
GOVERNMENT'S CASH PROBLEMS
COME CLOSER TO A POSSIBLE
RESOLUTION A REPORT ON THE
STAGGERING AMOUNT OF MONEY
THE GOVERNMENT SPENDS AND
WHETHER OR NOT THAT IS
SUSTAINABLE.
MARTHA: AS THE FUNERALS
CONTINUE TODAY FOR THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTING
VICTIMS THERE ARE NEW
QUESTIONS ABOUT HOW WE CAN
BETTER ADDRESS THIS SERIOUS
MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES THAT
HAVE LED TO THESE KINDS OF
TRAGEDIES ACROSS OUR
COUNTRY.
AS CONNECTICUT LAWMAKERS
PLEDGE TO TAKE MEANINGFUL
ACTION.
>> I DON'T WORRY THAT WE
CAN'T DO ANYTHING ABOUT IT.
WE CAN ALL IMAGINE NOAH AND
JACK STANDING RIGHT HERE,
6-YEAR-OLD BOYS, EASY FOR ME
WITH MY 10 TO 13-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHTERS KNOWING JACK AND
STANDING RIGHT HERE AND
SAYING, WILL YOU DO IT?
Hmm, it says here that Cheerios
helps lower cholesterol
as part
of a heart healthy diet.
That's true.
...But you still have to go
to the gym.
♪ The one and only, Cheerios
BILL: WE MENTIONED THIS
SEVEN MOMENTS AGO, SEVEN
MINUTES AGO I SHOULD SAY,
FOX NEWS ALERT.
APPARENTLY HOUSE SPEAKER
JOHN BOEHNER IS WORKING ON A
PLAN B THAT WOULD STOP THE
ALLIC TAX HIKES JANUARY 1st
IF WE DO NOT GET A FISCAL
CLIFF DEAL IN TIME.
THE CLOCK IS RUNNING.
CARL CAMERON, WHAT DO YOU
HAVE?
>> Reporter: BILL, WE WERE
TALKING A SHORT WHILE AGO
HOW MR. BOEHNER WAS GOING TO
TALK TO HIS RANK-AND-FILE
MEMBERS AND LEADERS BEHIND
CLOSED DOORS THIS MORNING AT
A MEETING THAT STARTED 9:00
ABOUT THE PRESIDENT'S OFFER
LAST NIGHT TO AGAIN TRY TO
RAISE REVENUE, DECREASE
SPENDING AND COME UP WITH A
BALANCED PLAN TO AVOID THE
FISCAL CLIFF OF MANDATORY
TAX INCREASES AND SPENDING
CUTS.
TURNS OUT THE REPUBLICANS
WERE PROBABLY GOING TO BE
APPREHENSIVE ABOUT IT, BUT
MR. BOEHNER WENT INTO THE
MEETING WITH ALTERNATIVE.
HE IS CONCERNED ABOUT THE
CALENDAR.
SO FAR INABILITY TO BREAK
THE JOG LAM ON A REAL DEAL
HERE.
THE DISTANCE BETWEEN THE TWO
SIDES.
AS A CONSEQUENCE HE TOLD HIS
MEMBERS HE HAS GOT A PLAN B.
I WANT TO READ REMARKS WE
KNOW HE IS SAYING BEHIND
CLOSED DOORS TO HIS FELLOW
REPUBLICANS.
HE WILL SAY OR HAS SAID,
QUOTE, FOR WEEKS SENATE
REPUBLICANS AND A GROWING
NUMBER OF YOU, MEANING HOUSE
REPUBLICANS HAVE BEEN
PUSHING FOR US TO PIVOT TO A
PLAN B I THINK THERE IS
BETTER WAY BUT THE
WHITE HOUSE CAN'T SEEM TO
BRING TO A BALANCED APPROACH
AND TIME IS RUNNING SHORT.
TAXES ARE GOING UP ON
EVERYONE JANUARY 1st.
THEY ARE BAKED INTO CURRENT
LAW AND WE HAVE TO STOP
WHATEVER RATE INCREASE WE
CAN IN THE ABSENCE OF
ALTERNATIVE THIS MORNING,
THIS MORNING A MODIFIED PLAN
B IS THE PLAN.
THAT PLAN B BOEHNER IS
PROPOSING TO HOUSE
REPUBLICANS COULD WOULD BE
VOTE IN THE HOUSE TO EXTEND
THE TAX REDUCTIONS OF THE
BUSH ERA ON EVERYBODY MAKING
UNDER A MILLION DOLLARS.
THAT WOULD POTENTIALLY AVERT
HAVING TAXES GO UP ON THE
FIRST OF THE YEAR AND
DAMAGING THE ECONOMY.
HOW THIS WOULD BE ARRANGED
WITH THE SENATE AND THE
PRESIDENT VERY MUCH UP IN
THE AIR BUT A CLEAR SIGN
FROM HOUSE REPUBLICANS THAT
THE TIME HAS ALL BUT RUN OUT
AND THEY NEED SOME SORT OF A
STOPGAP MEASURE TO AVERT
GOING OVER THE CLIFF,
HURTING THE ECONOMY WITH
MASSIVE TAX INCREASES AND
SPENDING REDUCTIONS
MANDATORY WITH SOME SORT OF
A STOPGAP.
WHETHER OR NOT THAT GOES
OVER WITH HOUSE REPUBLICANS.
DEMOCRATS SAY THIS OBVIOUSLY
WILL BE A BAD THING.
NEGOTIATIONS DO CONTINUE,
BILL.
BILL: THAT IS IMPORTANT
POINT.
I WANT TO EMPHASIZE
NEGOTIATIONS DO CONTINUE.
JUST SO OUR VIEWERS NO.
BOB CORKER IS AT THE TOP OF
THE 10:00 HOUR.
HE SAYS WE'RE NOWHERE NEAR A
DEAL.
WE'LL TALK WITH HIM ABOUT
THAT.
WE EXPECT TO HEAR FROM
SPEAKER BOEHNER AT 11:00
A.M. EASTERN TIME, CARL.
WE'LL BE IN TOUCH WITH YOU.
TIME'S A WASTING.
CARL CAMERON ON THE HILL.
MARTHA: THERE ARE SO MANY
NEW QUESTIONS NOW ABOUT HOW
SCHOOLS AND HOW SOCIETY CAN
BETTER ADDRESS THE ISSUE OF
MENTAL ILLNESS IN LIGHT OF
THE TRAGIC SCHOOL SHOOTING
IN CONNECTICUT.
ADAM LANZA REPORTEDLY
SUFFERED FROM MENTAL ILLNESS
ISSUES.
WE'RE STILL LEARNING TO WHAT
EXTENT THEY EXISTED AND FOR
HOW LONG THEY EXISTED BUT HE
IS CLEARLY NOT THE ONLY
GUNMAN IN THESE KINDS OF
RANDOM MASS SHOOTINGS THAT
WE HAVE SEEN WHO BATTLED
MENTAL DISORDERS.
WE'RE GOING TO TALK ABOUT
THAT.
HOW ABOUT THIS FROM
CONNECTICUT SENATOR
JOE LIEBERMAN?
HE SAYS HE BELIEVES FAMILY
AND FRIENDS NEED TO GET
INVOLVED IN THESE SITUATIONS
EARLY ON.
>> WE'VE GOT TO ASK PARENTS,
FRIENDS, SCHOOL FICIALTS, IF
YOU SEE A CHILD, A YOUNG
PERSON, THAT REALLY LOOKS
LIKE THEY'RE POTENTIALLY,
REALLY TROUBLESOME, GET THEM
MENTAL HEALTH HELP.
THEN WE'VE GOT TO ASK
OURSELVES AS A SOCIETY, IS
THERE ENOUGH MENTAL HEALTH
HELP AVAILABLE FOR THESE
KIDS?
>> BOY, THAT IS BECOMING THE
BIG IMPORTANT QUESTION IN
ALL OF OF THEM
CLEARLY.
I'M JOINED AS FORMER
PENNSYLVANIA GOVERNOR TOM
RIDGE WHO SERVED AS OUR
COUNTRY'S FIRST HOMELAND
SECURITY SECRETARY.
GOOD TO HAVE YOU HERE TODAY.
>> ALWAYS GOOD TO JOIN YOU,
MARTHA.
I'M SORRY WE JOINED TO HAVE
A DISCUSSION ABOUT THE
HORRIFIC EVENTS AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
MARTHA: IT IS SO
GUT-WRENCHING, WHEN YOU LOOK
DEEPER INTO THIS STORY.
AND PARTICULARLY WITH THIS
ISSUE OF MENTAL ILLNESS.
I WANT TO PULL UP ONTO THE
SCREEN A PICTURE OF SEVERAL
OF THESE YOUNG MEN.
THERE'S A PROFILE THAT
EMERGES IN THE COMMON
QUALITIES, ALL UNDER 25
YEARS OLD.
YOU'VE GOT CHO FROM THE
VIRGINIA TECH SHOOTING.
YOU HAVE ADAM LANZA ON THE
LEFT FROM CONNECTICUT.
YOU HAVE JIRD LOUGHNER FROM
THE TUCSON SHOOTING.
JAMES HOLMES FROM THE
AURORA, COLORADO, SHOOTING.
THERE ARE A LOT OF SIMILAR
CHARACTERISTICS IN THESE
YOUNG MEN.
ALL OF THEM HAD INTERVENTION
FROM SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST.
SEVERAL OF THEM TOOK
MEDICATION ON AND OFF.
WHAT DOES IT TELL US WHAT
WE'RE NOT DOING RIGHT IN
TERMS OF TREATING THESE
ISSUES?
>> FIRST OF ALL I THINK IT
IS VERY IMPORTANT THAT THE
DISCUSSION AROUND WHAT TO DO
FOCUSES NOT JUST ON THE
SECOND AMENDMENT.
PRECISELY ON THE PROFILE AND
TROUBLED PROFILES OF SO MANY
OF THESE ACTORS.
TO YOUR POINT, WHICH IS
WELL-STATED AND VERY
IMPORTANT IN THE NATIONAL
DISCUSSION, YOU TAKE A LOOK
AT THE INCIDENT AND COME
BACK AND TAKE A LOOK AT THE
INDIVIDUALS AND THERE IS,
WELL IT'S NOT UNIVERSALLY
APPLIED, THERE ARE MANY,
MANY INSTANCES WHERE THESE
YOUNG MEN HAD SERIOUS MENTAL
HEALTH PROBLEMS.
WHEN I SERVED ON THE
VIRGINIA TECH PANEL IT WAS
QUITE OBVIOUS CHO HIMSELF
HAD A DETERIORATING MENTAL
CONDITION THAT WAS
RECOGNIZED EARLY ON IN GRADE
SCHOOL AND HIGH SCHOOL.
FOLLOWED ALL THE WAY
THROUGH.
RECOGNIZED BY TEACHERS AND
RECOGNIZED BY A SPECIAL
JUSTICE HE WAS IN POTENTIAL
OF DANGER HARMING HIMSELF
AND THE COMMUNITY, YET THE
TREATMENT WAS INADEQUATE.
THIS IS REMINISCENT OF SOME
OF THE CHALLENGES WE HAD
SETTING UP HOMELAND SECURITY,
BALANCING INDIVIDUAL RIGHTS
WITH A NEED FOR COMMUNITIES
TO BE SAFE AND SECURE.
IT IS NOT JUST THE SECOND
AMENDMENT.
THERE IS A RIGHT OF PRIVACY.
THAT IS SOMETHING WE HAVE TO
LOOK AT VERY CAREFULLY
BECAUSE IT IS NOT IDENTIFIED
IN THE CONSTITUTION BUT IT
IS A RIGHT PEOPLE, THAT THE
LAWYERS AND THE SUPREME
COURT HAVE PROTECTED FOR A
LONG TIME BUT WE'VE GOT TO
FIND THE RIGHT BALANCE.
FIREARMS IN THE HANDS OF
MENTALLY DISABLED, MENTALLY
CHALLENGED INDIVIDUALS,
MAYBE BE AT THE EPICENTER OF
A LOT OF PROBLEMS WE HAVE
HAD.
MARTHA: YOU LOOK AT MENTAL
HEALTH AND HISTORY OF IT IN
THIS COUNTRY AND WE'VE
GOTTEN AWAY FROM THE TIME WE
HAD INSTITUTIONS AND PEOPLE
WERE COMMITTED TO AN
INSTITUTION IF THEIR
FAMILIES COULD NOT DEAL WITH
THEM.
THAT UNDERSTANDABLY RAN INTO
SOME BAD SITUATIONS WHERE
PEOPLE WERE COMMITTED.
THEY WERE IN INSTITUTIONS
THAT WERE HORRIBLE.
THAT WERE OFFENSIVE TO
EVERYBODY'S SENSIBILITY.
THEN WE GOT INTO A TIME
PERIOD WHERE WE WANTED TO
SORT OF MAINSTREAM
EVERYBODY.
EVERYBODY SHOULD BE ABLE TO
LIVE IN SOCIETY AND YOU KNOW,
HAVE THE SAME OPPORTUNITIES
EVERYONE ELSE HAS.
NOW YOU HAVE A SITUATION
WHERE, THERE'S A VERY
POIGNANT BLOG THAT WENT OUT
THIS MORNING BY A WOMAN WHO
IS STRUGGLING WITH A CHILD
WHO SHE SAYS IS THE NEXT
ADAM LANZA, OKAY?
AND THE DESPERATION THAT
THIS MOTHER FEELS IN THE
LACK OF ABILITY TO GET HELP.
I WANT TO READ SOME OF THIS
MOTHER'S BLOG TO YOU THIS
MORNING.
SHE SAYS, NO ONE WANTS TO
SEND A 13-YEAR-OLD GENIUS
WHO LOVES "HARRY POTTER" AND
HIS SNUGGLE ANIMAL
COLLECTION TO JAIL BUT OUR
SOCIETY WITH ITS STIGMA ON
MENTAL ILLNESS AND ITS
BROKEN HEALTH CARE SYSTEM
DOES NOT PROVIDE US WITH
OTHER OPTIONS.
THEN ANOTHER TORTURED SOUL
SHOOTS UP A FAST-FOOD
RESTAURANT, A MALL, A
KINDERGARTEN CLASSROOM AND
SHE GOES ON TO SAY WE WRING
OUR HANDS AND SAY SOMETHING
MUST BE DONE.
THIS POOR MOTHER SHOWED UP
AT HOSPITAL, SAID I NEED
HELP.
SOMEONE TAKE MY CHILD.
HE IS THREATENING TO KILL MY
OTHER CHILDREN AND ME.
THE NEXT DAY HE IS DOCILE,
AND HAPPY, MOMMY I WILL BE
BETTER, I PROMISE.
WHAT CAN WE OFFER THIS
WOMAN?
>> FIRST OF ALL SHE IS HERRO
ININ MY MIND, SHE RAISED IN
A PUBLIC WAY A SITUATION A
LOT OF PARENTS WOULD BE VERY
DIFFICULT FOR THEM TO RAISE,
PUBLIC RECOGNITION THAT
THEIR SON HAS A MENTAL
HEALTH CHALLENGE.
SHE ALSO USED A WORD VERY
APPROPRIATE.
IT IS WHY IT NEEDS TO BE
PART OF THE NATIONAL
DISCUSSION.
WE STIGMATIZE YOUNG PEOPLE
WITH MENTAL HEALTH PROBLEMS
INSTEAD OF RECEIVING OUT
TRYING TO HELP THEM.
CLEARLY, CLEARLY THE MENTAL
HEALTH COMMUNITY HAS BEEN
ADEQUATELY STAFF,
INADEQUATELY FUNDED FOR A
LONG TIME.
NOT THAT EVERYBODY NEEDS TO
BE INSTITUTIONALIZED.
NOT EVERYBODY NEEDS TO BE
PUT ON A DRUG REGIMEN.
THE FACT OF MATTER REMAINS
VARIOUS DEGREES OF MENTAL
HEALTH ILLNESS HAVE TO BE
RECOGNIZED AND DEALT WITH.
I LOVE JOE LIEBERMAN'S CALL
FOR PARENTS AND FRIENDS TO
RECOGNIZE THESE PROBLEM AND
DIRECT THESE YOUNG PEOPLE TO
HELP.
THE PATTERN OF ACTIVITY YOU
REPORTED, A LOT OF
INDIVIDUALS INVOLVED IN
THESE MASS MURDERS HAVE
TALKED ABOUT SUICIDE.
THEY HAVE TALKED ABOUT
KILLING OTHER PEOPLE BUT CAN
YOU THINK IN THIS DAY AND
AGE, THIS GENERATION DO YOU
WANT TO SNITCH ON YOUR BUDDY
WHO TALKED ABOUT DOING
SOMETHING LIKE THAT?
IT IS CULTURAL PROBLEM AND
MENTAL HEALTH PROBLEM.
WE BETTER ADDRESS IT SOON
AND SERIOUSLY.
MARTHA: ONE OF THE ISSUES IF
SOMEONE HASN'T BEEN CHARGED
WITH ANY CRIME AS ADAM LANZA
WAS NOT.
HE WASN'T EVEN ON THE RADAR
OF THE LAW ENFORCEMENT
PEOPLE IN HIS NEIGHBORHOOD
AND TOWN, YOU HAVE VERY
LITTLE RECOURSE AS A PARENT
IN TERMS OF HELP.
BREAK YOUR LEG, YOU GO TO AN
EMERGENCY ROOM YOU WILL GET
IT FIXED BUT IF YOU HAVE A
CHILD WHO IS THREATENING TO
KILL YOUR OTHER CHILDREN OR
ANYONE ELSE, YOU HAVE VERY
LITTLE RECOURSE.
IT IS REALLY IMPORTANT TOPIC
WE NEED TO ADDRESS HERE.
THANKS SO MUCH FOR TALKING
ABOUT IT TOM RIDGE.
MERRY CHRISTMAS TO YOU AND
YOUR FAMILY.
>> THANK YOU, MARTHA.
BILL: QUICK CHECK OF THE
MARKETS RIGHT NOW, WE'RE UP
ABOUT 19 POINTS.
THERE IS GROWING OPTIMISM ON
A DEAL.
OH, YEAH?
WE MIGHT FIND OUT IN 20
MINUTES OR SO.
WE'RE WAITING FOR THE HOUSE
SPEAKER AND SENATOR BOB
CORKER OUT OF TENNESSEE.
CORKER SAYS I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU GUYS ARE TALKING
ABOUT, WE'RE A LONG WAY FROM
A DEAL ON THIS THING.
THE MARKETS ARE UP, THAT IS
GOOD NEWS.
THE REPUBLICANS MEETING ON
THE PRESIDENT'S OFFER.
IF THE SPEAKER GIVES TOO
MUCH WILL REPUBLICANS PAY A
HEFTY PRICE?
WILL REPUBLICANS EVEN GO
ALONG WITH HIM IN THE HOUSE?
WE'LL DEBATE IT.
MARTHA: AND NEW DETAILS ON
THIS VERY IMPORTANT STORY
THIS MORNING.
THIS IS A U.S. MARINE WHO
LOCKED UP IN A NOTORIOUS
MEXICAN PRISON AND CHAINED
TO HIS BED AS HIS FAMILY
PLEADS AND SAYS THIS IS A
HUGE MISTAKE.
THEY WANT HELP FROM THE
GOVERNMENT.
>> EXAMINE THIS CASE.
THIS IS WRONG, AND DO THE
RIGHT THING.
HE SHOULD BE RELEASED
IMMEDIATELY.
THIS WAS AN ADMINISTRATIVE
MISTAKE.
HE IS NOT A GUNRUNNER.
AND YOU KNOW IT.
PLEASE RELEASE HIM.
Feeling isolated because your
family and friends find it
difficult to talk with you?
Discover the Siemens difference
with Eclipse,
a giant leap forward in hearing
technology
Eclipse hearing aids are
fine-tuned with such precision
they're like high-definition for
your ears.
Hear rich, crystal-clear sound
without that muffled-effect you
get with other hearing aids.
So now you can connect with
family and friends again
effortlessly.
Siemens Eclipse fit so
comfortably
and are nearly invisible
They'll change your life.
Eclipse from Siemens:
pure, natural sound you're going
to love the moment you put them
on
and for many years to come.
Call...
for a special $200 rebate.
That number again...
and discover Siemens Eclipse
hearing aids today.
This reduced sodium soup
says it mahelp
lower cholesterol,
how does it work?
You just he to eat it as part
of your heart healthy diet.
Step 1. Eat the soup.
All those
veggies and beans,
that's what may help
lower your cholesterol and --
Well that's easy
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
BILL: HERE WE GO.
WE'RE AWAITING HOUSE SPEAKER
JOHN BOEHNER.
HE WILL BE AT THE MICROPHONE
IN A MATTER OF MOMENTS.
PLAN B APPARENTLY MIGHT BE
ON THE TABLE AS A BACKUP TO
STOP TAXES FROM GOING UP
BEFORE THE FIRST OF THE YEAR,
IN LIEU OF NOT ARRIVING AT A
DEAL.
WE'RE HEARING THAT THE
WHITE HOUSE AND SPEAKER ARE
CLOSER.
WHAT'S TRUE?
WHO KNOWS.
BOB BECKEL, FORMER
DEMOCRATIC CAMPAIGN MANAGER.
ANDREA TANTEROS, DAILY NEWS
COLUMNIST, BOTH CO-HOST OF
"THE FIVE." GOOD MORNING TO
BOTH OF YOU.
HAPPY ANNIVERSARY.
>> HAPPY ANNIVERSARY?
>> THANK YOU, BILL.
BILL: BOB HAS NO IDEA WHAT
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT.
>> LIKE ANY MAN CELEBRATING
AN ANNIVERSARY.
BILL: IT WAS THIS WEEK FIVE
YEARS AGO WHERE THE TWO OF
YOU CAME ON TV FOR THE FIRST
TIME.
>> HAS IT BEEN THAT LONG?
BILL: IT HAS BEEN THAT LONG.
THE TIME HAS FLOWN.
AND WHAT PEOPLE, PEOPLE ARE
NOT GIVING US ANY CREDIT FOR
CREATING "THE FIVE." WHICH
EVENTUALLY LED TO THAT.
>> FRANCHISE STARTED RIGHT
HERE.
>> HAPPY ANNIVERSARY, ANDREA,
BILL.
YOU DID A TERRIFIC JOB IN
CONNECTICUT.
I CAN'T TELL YOU.
>> YES YOU DID, BILL.
BILL: TOUGH STORY AS YOU CAN
WELL SEE.
>> I COULDN'T IMAGINE.
BILL: LET'S TALK ABOUT THIS
ANDREA.
WILL REPUBLICANS GO ALONG
WITH BOEHNER OR TELL HIM TO
GET OUT OF THE ROOM AGAIN?
>> IT DEPENDS WHAT HE IS
PROPOSING.
IF HE IS PROPOSING TO HAVE A
VOTE EXTENDING ALL THE BUSH
TAX CUTS THERE IS A VERY
GOOD CHANCE THEY WILL GO
ALONG WITH HIM BUT WHY
DIDN'T HE DO THIS EARLIER? I
SAID IT ON THE "THE FIVE"
LAST WEEK.
MY FIRST SUGGESTION, MY PLAN
A WAS WALK AWAY LET OBAMA
OWN IT.
AS WE CAN SEE HE IS
CONCEDING NOTHING.
BUT THE PLAN B FROM THE
START, PASS YOUR OWN PLAN,
AND THEN LEAVE AND GET YOUR
GUYS ON RECORD, YOUR GUYS
AND GALS IN THE HOUSE GOP
CONFERENCE ON RECORD WITH
SOMETHING THEY CAN TAKE BACK
TO THEIR DISTRICT.
A LOT OF THESE MEMBERS, BILL,
ARE PETRIFIED TO VOTE FOR
INCREASED TAXES BECAUSE
THINK ABOUT IT.
THEY HAVE TO RUN FOR
RE-ELECTION IN TWO YEARS.
THEY'RE FEARING THE
PRIMARIES FROM PEOPLE ON THE
RIGHT.
SO PASS YOUR OWN BILL AND
LET HARRY REID HAVE THE GUTS
TO BRING IT TO THE FLOOR.
I DOUBT HE WILL.
BILL: WHERE ARE YOU ON THIS
TODAY, BOB?
>> FIRST OF ALL I THINK
REPUBLICANS WOULD PAY A
PRICE FOR NOT GOING ALONG
WITH THIS.
THE IDEA OF A MILLION,
MILLIONAIRE TAX BASICALLY
WHAT WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
HERE IS SOMETHING I CAN NOT
IMAGINE THERE ARE TOO MANY
MILLIONAIRES IN MOST OF
THESE DISTRICTS.
FROM A POLITICAL STANDPOINT
HAVE EVERYBODY GET A TAX ON
1st OF JANUARY THEY WOULD
BLAME THE REPUBLICANS NO
QUESTION ABOUT IT.
PRESS WOULD.
I WOULD.
MOST OF DEMOCRATS AND
PRESIDENT WOULD.
HERE'S THE DEAL.
OF COURSE BOEHNER WILL HAVE
TO GET SOMETHING FOR THIS.
THE QUESTION IS IT ON
ENTITLEMENTS?
YES.
CAN YOU GET ENTITLEMENTS
WRITTEN BY END OF THIS YEAR?
OF COURSE NOT.
WHAT HAS TO BE WHATEVER THE
DEAL IS SOME DATE CERTAIN
WHEN THEY REPORT OUT A
CHANGE TO ENTITLEMENTS WITH
SOME FIGURE ATTACHED TO IT.
NOW, AND IF NOT THEY COULD
COME BACK AND, UNDO THE TAX
RATE INCREASE.
THAT IS ONLY WAY I COULD SEE
THEY DO IT.
>> THE PROBLEM IS --.
BILL: DID YOU WANT TO
RESPOND, ANDREA I'M SORRY?
IT IS YOUR ANNIVERSARY.
I SHOULD RESPECT THAT.
>> WHERE IS THE CAKE, RIGHT?
WE'LL GET CELEBRATE A DEAL.
THERE.
I DON'T THINK THERE IS
POLITICAL APPETITE IN
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S CAUCUS TO
GET THE MEMBERS TO AGREE ON
SOME FORM OF ENTITLEMENTS.
FRANKLY, BILL, THE PRESIDENT
HAS CONCEDED NOTHING.
BILL: LET ME MAKE THIS
POINT.
YOU GUYS CAN REACT TO IT.
AND THERE'S A LOT OF
REPORTING ABOUT THIS
THROUGHOUT THE MORNING.
THEY'RE TALKING ABOUT A DEAL
THAT WILL SAVE $2 TRILLION
OVER 10 YEARS.
WE'RE ALREADY AT 16
TRILLION.
WE'LL BE AT 20 TRILLION IN
FOUR YEARS FOR SURE.
SAVING $2 TRILLION?
OVER THE NEXT 10 YEARS?
WE'RE LEFT WITH A HUGE BAG
ON OUR HANDS AT THE END OF
THAT DEAL ANYWAY, AREN'T WE,
BOB?
>> YEAH.
FIRST OF ALL, FUNNY WHAT YOU
SAY 2 TRILLION IF IT IS
TRUMP CHANGE.
IN THIS DAY AND AGE IT SEEMS
LIKE THAT.
BILL: RIDICULOUS, RIGHT.
>> WHAT YOU DON'T INCLUDE
ENTITLEMENT CUTS WHICH THERE
WILL BE.
HERE IS ANSWER FOR
DEMOCRATIC CAUCUS, IF
REPUBLICANS GO ALONG WITH
TAX RATE INCREASES ON RICH
THEN THE DEMOCRATS IF THEY
DON'T DO SOMETHING ON
ENTITLEMENTS WILL TAKE
POLITICAL HEAT FOR IT.
BILL: ALL RIGHT.
ANDREA.
DO YOU AGREE WITH THAT?
>> I THINK THAT BOB IS BEING
ACTUALLY REASONABLE AT THIS
MOMENT AND HE HAS SOME GOOD
IDEAS THAT HE MENTIONED
BEFORE LIKE RAISING AGE OF
ELIGIBILITY, BUT I DON'T
THINK A LOT OF MEMBERS IN
THE DEMOCRATIC CAUCUS WILL
GO ALONG WITH IT.
I DON'T.
AS FAR AS RAISING TAXES ON
RICH, BOB, THEY STILL CAN'T
AGREE WHAT IS RICH.
IS IT GOING TO BE MILLION
DOLLARS?
PRESIDENT SAYS 400,000.
AND I DO AGREE WITH YOU ON
ONE POINT, BOB, REPUBLICANS
DO NOT WANT TO LOOK LIKE
THEY'RE PROTECTING THE RICH
BUT I THINK THEY FIGURE
WE'RE GETTING BLAMED ANYWAY
SO WE MIGHT AS WELL STAND UP
FOR --.
BILL: SORRY, GUYS.
WE DID NOT, WE'LL GET TO
THAT IN A MOMENT.
SPEAKER BOEHNER AT THE TOP
THE HOUR.
BOB CORKER, SPUB REPUBLICAN
SENATOR FROM TENNESSEE WILL
BE OUR GUEST IN 10 MINUTES.
HE SAYS TODAY, WE'RE NOT
CLOSE.
I'M SURPRISED AT REPORTING
TODAY.
UNLESS SOMETHING HAPPENED AT
6:00 A.M. WE'RE NOT CLOSE TO
A DEAL.
WE'LL GET HIS REACTION.
SEE YOU GUYS ON "THE FIVE".
FROM US TO YOU, HAPPY
ANNIVERSARY.
>> THANK YOU, BILL.
BILL: FIVE YEARS TOGETHER.
>> AND YOU WHO PUT THE
THREESOME TOGETHER.
BILL: LIKE PETER, PAUL AND
MARY.
BYE-BYE.
MARTHA: THANKS YOU GUYS.
THIS IS EXACTLY WHAT YOU
WERE JUST TALKING ABOUT.
HOW MUCH COMES INTO THE
GOVERNMENT COFFERS AND HOW
MUCH MORE GOES OUT?
WE ALL KNOW ONE NUMBER IS A
LOT BIGGER THAN THE OTHER,
RIGHT?
WHERE DO YOUR TAX DOLLARS
GO?
A SHOCKING LOOK.
BILL: ALSO ONE OF A KIND
TRAINING FACILITY FOR LAW
ENFORCEMENT GETTING READY
FOR ANY POSSIBLE TERROR
THREAT THAT MAY BE COMING
YOUR WAY.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
MARTHA: WELL THE WHITE HOUSE
AND CONGRESS TRYING TO
STRIKE A BALANCE BETWEEN
SPENDING CUTS AND TAX
INCREASES.
YOU'VE HEARD THAT, RIGHT?
THINK ABOUT THIS.
EVERY DAY THE GOVERNMENT
TAKES IN $6 BILLION AND IT
SPENDS 10 DAL BILLION.
SO WHERE IS ALL THAT MONEY
ACTUALLY GOING?
DOUG McKELWAY IS LIVE IN
WASHINGTON WITH A CLOSER
LOOK AT THE COST OF ALL THAT
SPENDING.
MY, MY.
HEY, DOUG.
>> Reporter: MARTHA, GOOD
MORNING TO YOU.
VIRTUALLY EVERY PRESIDENT
SINCE REAGAN TALKED ABOUT
THE NEED TO REDUCE DEFICIT
SPENDING OF THE PRESIDENT
OBAMA IS NO EXCEPTION.
>> I'VE SHOWN MYSELF WILLING
TO MAKE THE TOUGH DECISIONS
WHEN IT COMES TO GOVERNMENT
SPENDING.
>> Reporter: BUT IN TALKS TO
AVOID THE FISCAL CLIFF
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER INSISTS
THAT THE PRESIDENT'S ACTIONS
SPEAK VERY DIFFERENTLY THAN
HIS WORDS.
>> IT'S CLEAR THE PRESIDENT
IS JUST NOT SERIOUS ABOUT
CUTTING SPENDING BUT
SPENDING IS THE PROBLEM.
>> Reporter: SO HOW BIG OF A
PROBLEM?
LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT LAST
NOVEMBER ALONE.
EACH DAY THAT MONTH THE
GOVERNMENT BROUGHT IN ABOUT
$5 BILLION OF REVENUE BUT WE
SPENT MORE THAN $11 BILLION
A IN NOVEMBER.
THE DIFFERENCE?
OBVIOUSLY $6 BILLION.
HERE'S WHERE MOST OF THAT
MONEY GOES.
THE TOP FOUR OUTLAYS.
AT TOP OF THE LIST THE
DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND
HUMAN SERVICES WHICH GOES
THROUGH $3 BILLION OF YOUR
TAX AS DAY.
SOCIAL SECURITY IS CLOSE
SECOND AT $2.5 BILLION
DAILY.
MILITARY PROGRAMS COME IN AT
1.8 BILLION DAILY.
BUT ECONOMISTS SAY MOST
CONCERNING IS THE INTEREST
ON THE DEBT.
RIGHT NOW IT IS AT $854
MILLION A DAY.
AND AS INTEREST RATES RISE
THAT NUMBER GOES UP,
CREATING POTENTIAL SNOWBALL
EFFECT OF CREATING MORE TO
BORROW MORE.
>> THIS IS NOT THEORETICAL.
THIS IS NOT A CLASSROOM
EXERCISE.
YOU LOOK AT EUROPE AND SEE
WHAT HAPPENS IF WE CONTINUE
DOWN THIS PATH VERY MUCH
LONGER THAT IS PLACE WE
DON'T WANT TO GO.
>> Reporter: PRIMARY DRIVER
OF ALL THE DEBT SPENDING,
MEDICARE, MEDICAID, AND
SOCIAL SECURITY.
AND A NATION UNWILLING TO
REIN IN THEIR COSTS.
>> IT'S LIKE YOUR
RESPONSIBLE BROTHER-IN-LAW
RUNS UP THE CREDIT CARDS AND
GOES BUST AND SAYS THE REAL
PROBLEM IS BECAUSE YOU
STOPPED SENDING ME CHECKS.
>> Reporter: BROOKS SAYS WE
HAVE BECOME A DEBTOR NATION
WITH A MENTALITY THAT SAYS
IF WE CAN SQUEEZE MORE MONEY
OUT OF PEOPLE WHO ARE
WORKING THAT CAN SOLVE THE
PROBLEM.
HE SAYS THAT IS SIMPLY NOT
SO.
MARTHA?
MARTHA: INTERESTING.
SAD, INTERESTING.
I DON'T KNOW WHETHER TO
LAUGH OR CRY.
THANK YOU.
BILL: THERE IS A COLLEGE
FRESHMAN FOUND DEAD AT A
FRATERNITY HOUSE.
NOW 20 MEMBERS OF THE GROUP
FACING CRIMINAL CHARGES, 20.
WE'LL TELL YOU WHY.
TO THE BEST VACATION
SPOT ON EARTH.
(ALL) THE GULF!
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHICH OF
OUR GREAT STATES FOLKS VISIT.
MISSISSIPPI,
ALABAM
LOUISIANA
OR FLORIDA,
THEY'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
SHAUL, YOUR ALABAMA
HOSPITALITY IS INCREDIBLE.
THANKS, KAREN.
LOVE YOUR MISSISSIPPI OUTDOORS.
I VOTE FOR YOUR
FLORIDA BEACHES, DAWN.
BILL, THIS LOUISIANA
SEAFOOD IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR ON THE GULF,
WE'VE DECIDED TO PUT
ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
NOW IS THE PERFECT TIME TO
VISIT ANYONE OF OUR STATES.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE, GO FISHING
OR JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
WE'VE GOT COASTLINE TO EXPLORE
AND WILDLIFE TO PHOTOGRAPH.
AND THERE'S WORLD CLASS DINING
WITH OUR WORLD FAMOUS SEAFOOD.
SO FOR A GREAT VACATION
THIS YEAR, COME TO THE GULF.
ITS ALL FABULOUS BUT
I GIVE FLORIDA THE EDGE.
RIGHT AFTER MISSISSIPPI.
YOU MEAN ALABAMA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
THIS INVITATION IS
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP
AND ALL OF US WHO
CALL THE GULF HOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE RHYTHM OF LIFE.
[ whistle blowing ]
WHERE DO YOU HEAR THAT BEAT?
CAMPBELL'S HEALTHY REQUEST SOUP
LETS YOU HEAR IT...
IN YOUR HEART.
[ basketball bouncing ]
HEART HEALTHY.
GREAT TASTE.
MMM...
[ Male Announcer ] SOUNDS GOOD.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT STARTED LONG AGO.
THE JOY OF GIVING SOMETHING
EVERYTHING YOU'VE GOT.
IT TAKES PASSION.
AND IT'S NOT LETTING UP
ANYTIME SOON.
AT UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company,
WE UNDERSTAND THAT COMMITMENT.
AND ALWAYS HAVE.
SO DOES AARP,
AN ORGANIZATION
SERVING THE NEEDS
OF AMERICANS 50 AND OVER
FOR GENERATIONS.
SO IT'S NO SURPRISE
MILLIONS HAVE CHOSEN
AN AARP Medicare Supplement
Insurance Plan,
INSURED BY UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company.
LIKE ALL STANDARDIZED
MEDICARE SUPPLEMENT PLANS,
THEY HELP COVER
SOME OF THE EXPENSES
MEDICARE DOESN'T PAY.
AND SAVE YOU UP TO THOUSANDS
IN OUT-OF-POCKET COSTS.
TO FIND OUT MORE,
REQUEST YOUR
FREE DECISION GUIDE.
CALL OR GO ONLINE TODAY.
AFTER ALL,
WHEN YOU'RE GOING THE DISTANCE,
IT'S NICE TO HAVE
THE EXPERIENCE AND COMMITMENT
TO GO ALONG WITH YOU.
KEEP DREAMING. KEEP DOING.
GO LONG.
MARTHA: GETTING READY FOR NEWS
ON THE FISCAL CLIFF ISSUE HERE
THIS MORNING.
IT IS PLAN B FOR REPUBLICAN
LEADERS WHO ARE HOPING TO AVOID
LOOMING TAX HIKES IN CASE A
FISCAL CLIFF DEAL FAILS BEFORE
JANUARY THE 1st.
WAITING FOR AN UPDATE RIGHT NOW,
EXPECT TO GET IT ANY MINUTE.
BOTH REPUBLICANS AND DEMOCRATS,
JOHN BOEHNER MEETING WITH HIS
CAUCUS TO SELL THE PLAN B ISSUE,
KEEPING TAXES THE SAME FOR
ANYONE UNDER A MILLION DOLLARS A
YEAR.
WE HAVE HEARD THE PRESIDENT IS
AT 400,000 ON THAT NUMBER.
THEY ARE MOVING TOWARDS THE
MIDDLE.
I'M MARTHA MACCALLUM.
BRAND-NEW HOUR OF "AMERICA'S
NEWSROOM."
BILL: I'M BILL HEMMER.
NEGOTIATIONS CONTINUE.
WE ARE TOLD WITH THE WHITE HOUSE
THEY CONTINUE ON A BROADER TAX
AND SPENDING DEAL.
WILL THEY GET THAT DEAL?
BOB CORKER OUT OF TENNESSEE
MEMBER OF THE SENATE COMMITTEE
MY GUEST NOW.
I'M GOING TO USE YOUR WORDS,
WE'RE NOT CLOSE.
>> NO.
BILL: TELL ME.
>> THE PRESIDENT HAS YET TO
LAYOUT TANGIBLE ENTITLEMENT
REFORMS.
BILL, I'VE BEEN TRYING TO GET US
TO PIVOT TO THAT FOR ALMOST A
MONTH NOW AND HE WANTS A DEBT
CEILING INCREASE, AND DO AWAY
WITH THE SEQUESTER BUT HE
DOESN'T WANT TO LAYOUT TANGIBLE
ENTITLEMENT REFORMS.
WE ARE NOT EVEN CLOSE TO A DEAL
IN MY OPINION.
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER HAS DONE
EVERYTHING POSSIBLE TO PUT THIS
ISSUE IN THE REAR VIEW MIRROR SO
WE CAN START JANUARY 1st
FOCUSED ON GROWING OUR ECONOMY.
UNFORTUNATELY THE WHITE HOUSE IS
STILL NOT COMING FORTH WITH I
THINK AT LEAST A TRILLION
DOLLARS IN ENTITLEMENT REFORMS
ARE NEEDED RIGHT NOW TO CAUSE
OUR COUNTRY TO BE ABLE TO MOVE
BEYOND THIS.
AT PRESENT THERE IS NOTHING
TANGIBLE.
WHAT THEY ARE OFFERING IS A
FISCAL CLIFF A YEAR FROM NOW
WITH UNDETERMINED COST CUTTING.
BILL: LET ME TROY AND CUT
THROUGH TRY AND CUT THROUGH A
COUPLE OF THINGS RIGHT HERE.
YOU'RE SAYING THE DEAL CANNOT GO
FORWARD BECAUSE THERE IS NOT
ENOUGH ENTITLEMENT REFORM.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
BILL: THE HOUSE IS SET TO MOVE
ON A BILL POSSIBLY TODAY OR
LATER ON THE WEEK, TO RESCUE THE
BULK OF THE COUNTRY FROM A TAX
INCREASE.
THEN YOU SAY UNFORTUNATELY THAT
IS THE ONLY THING THAT WILL
HAPPEN THIS YEAR.
IF THAT IS THE ONLY THING THAT
HAPPENS THIS YEAR, THEN TAXES DO
GO UP BU UP ON EVERYBODY WHO
MAKES LESS THAN A MILLION
DOLLARS A YEAR.
THE HOUSE REPUBLICANS FIGHTING
THIS BATTLE FOR YEARS NOW WILL
GO INTO THE NEW YEAR AND WILL
HAVE VOTED ON A MEASURE IN THE
END TO RAISE TAXES.
>> NO, THERE IS A WAY, BILL,
THAT THEY CAN VOTE AND NOT RAISE
TAXES.
THEY CAN ACTUALLY VOTE TO FREEZE
EVERYBODY'S TAXES.
THEY CAN VOTE TO FREEZE
EVERYBODY UNDER A MILLION.
BILL: FOR EVERYONE.
>> YEAH.
WHAT CAN HAPPEN IS ALL OF THEM
CAN VOTE TO KEEP THE BUSH TAX
CUTS IN PLACE, AND WHEN IT COMES
OVER TO THE SENATE THEN THE
SENATE CHANGES IT, OBVIOUSLY I'D
BE VOTING THE WAY THE HOUSE
MEMBERS HAVE VOTED, BUT, NO,
THERE IS A WAY OF DOING THAT
WITHOUT THEM ACTUALLY VOTING FOR
ANY KIND OF TAX INCREASE.
BILL: I WANT TO BE CLEAR ABOUT
THAT.
THE WAY I READ YOUR COMMENT FROM
EARLIER TODAY SUGGESTED THAT
HOUSE REPUBLICANS WOULD VOTE ON
RAISING TAXES.
>> NO.
BILL: WHETHER IT'S A MILLIONAIRE
OR WHETHER IT'S NOT.
THEN YOU GO INTO THE NEW YEAR
THAT IS THE ONLY THING YOU GET
ACCOMPLISHED NOW.
>> IT'S UNFORTUNATE.
I DON'T KNOW HOW, THOUGH, BILL,
THAT YOU CAN AGREE TO GIVE AWAY
THE DEBT CEILING INCREASE TO
THIS PRESIDENT WHO IS RED LINING
OUR COUNTRY WITH SPENDING RIGHT
NOW.
HE WANTS US TO GIVE AWAY THE
DEBT CEILING, DO AWAY WITH THE
SEQUESTER WHICH IS 1.2 TRILLION
IN REDUCTIONS OVER THE NEXT
DECADE AND ALL HE'S LAYING ON
THE TABLE IS 400 BILLION IN
REDUCTIONS THAT ARE SPECIFIC,
ONLY 200 BILLION OF THOSE ARE
ENTITLEMENTS AND ANOTHER TO BE
TKERPD DISCUSSION THAT LEND IN
ANOTHER FISCAL CLIFF IN A YEAR.
SO, BILL I THINK WHAT THE HOUSE
IS SAYING IS THAT LOOK, WE
REALIZE THAT WE REALIZE WHERE WE
ARE, WE WANT TO RESCUE EVERYBODY
WHO MAKES UNDER A MILLION
DOLLARS.
THEY ARE STILL NOT GOING TO VOTE
FOR ANY TAX INCREASE.
THERE IS A WAY THEY CAN DO
THAT.
UNFORTUNATELY WE'LL CARRY THIS
ONTO THE DEBT CEILING AND
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER HAS BEEN
TRYING TO RESOLVE THIS.
I THINK HE'S BEEN A HERO IN
THIS.
BUT THE PRESIDENT STILL IS NOT
FORTHCOMING, BILL, WITH ANY
TANGIBLE ENTITLEMENT REFORMS.
WITHOUT THAT YOU CANNOT SAVE OUR
COUNTRY WITHOUT DOING THAT.
BILL: I'M READING THROUGH A LOT
OF THE REPORTS.
LET ME -- THE AMOUNT OF SPENDING
YOU'LL SAVE IN TEN YEARS WHICH
AMOUNTS TO $2 TRILLION.
WHEN YOU CONSIDER IN FOUR YEAR'S
TIME WE'LL BE AT $20 TRILLION.
IT'S SUCH A SMALL AMOUNT.
YOU'RE GOING TO GO INTO THE NEW
YEAR AND NONE OF THIS GETS
ACCOMPLISHED.
>> AND YOU'LL HAVE THE DEBT
CEILING IN FEBRUARY OR MARCH
WHICH WILL BE A WHOLE OTHER
ROUND OF DISCUSSION.
BILL: WHAT IS THE IMPACT AND
THAT IS THE CASE AND REALITY AND
THE WAY IT PLAYS OUT, IS THE
IMPACT ON OUR ECONOMY.
>> IT'S TERRIBLE, ABSOLUTELY
TERRIBLE, BILL.
I LAID OUT A BILL ABOUT THREE
WEEKS AGO THAT SPECIFICALLY SAID
THE THINGS THAT WE NEEDED TO DO
AS A NATION, AND I DON'T THINK
ANYBODY ELSE HAS ACTUALLY DONE
THAT IN LEGISLATIVE LANGUAGE.
WHAT THIS NATION NEEDS IS TO PUT
THIS IN THE REAR VIEW MIRROR,
COME UP WITH 4 1/2 TO
$5 TRILLION OF REFORMS AND
SAVINGS AND CUTS TO REALLY LOWER
THE DEFICIT THAT YOU'RE TALKING
ABOUT.
BY THE WAY IN THE OUT YEARS,
BILL, IF YOU MAKE ENTITLEMENT
REFORMS THE NUMBERS ARE TENS OF
TRILLIONS OF DOLLARS AND YOU
SAVE THOSE PROGRAMS FOR FUTURE
GENERATIONS.
NO IT'S AN ABSOLUTE TRAVESTY
THAT WE ARE WHERE WE ARE, WE ARE
A GREAT NATION, EVERY DEVELOPED
COUNTRY IN THE WORLD KNOWS OUR
GREATEST THREAT IS OUR OWN
FISCAL SOLVENCY AND WE HAVE A
PRESIDENT THAT WE HAVE TO TRY TO
LEVERAGE INTO A PLACE OF DOING
THE THINGS THAT ARE NECESSARY
FOR OUR COUNTRY.
IT'S A TRAVESTY.
WHAT THIS MEANS IS THERE ARE
AMERICANS OF ALL WALKS OF LIFE
THAT WILL NOT SEE THE ECONOMIC
PROSPECTS THIS NEXT YEAR THAT
OTHERWISE THEY WOULD HAVE SEEN,
BECAUSE THIS PRESIDENT IS
UNWILLING TO LAYOUT A CONE
WREATH PLAN TCONCRETE PLAN TO
SAVE THIS NATION.
I THINK SPEAKER BOEHNER HAS BEEN
TRYING TO GET THERE.
I THINK IT'S A TRAVESTY.
BILL: THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME.
BOB CORKER IS A REPUBLICAN FROM
TENNESSEE.
MARTHA: YOU THINK ABOUT THE FEAR
THAT WE COULD GO OVER THIS
FISCAL CLIFF, AND THAT THE
FUTURE LOOKS VERY DARK IF WE ARE
NOT ABLE TO GET OUR HANDS AROUND
THE DEBT THAT YOU ALL WERE JUST
DISCUSSING.
NOW WE ARE LEARNING THAT ERIC
CANTOR HAS TOLD THE CAUCUS THAT
THERE WILL BE A VOTE LIKELY ON A
REPUBLICAN FISCAL CLIFF TAX PLAN
IN THE HOUSE THAT COULD COME
THIS WEEK.
THAT DOESN'T NECESSARILY MOVE
THE BALL ALONG TOO DRAMATICALLY
IN THIS PICTURE, BECAUSE
EVERYBODY KNOWS THAT THE
REPUBLICAN SIDE IN THE HOUSE IS
GOING TO VOTE ON A DEAL THAT
WOULD HAVE A LOT OF SPENDING
CUTS IN IT AND IT'S SOMETHING
THAT THE PRESIDENT WOULD BE
UNLIKELY TO SIGN INTO LAW.
WE ARE WAITING FOR JOHN BOEHNER
TO COME IN RIGHT NOW.
HE'LL BE WITH THE USUAL TEAM.
KEVIN MCCARTHY WILL BE THERE,
KATHY MCMORRIS, PEOPLE WORKING
TO HOLD THE FISCAL LINE AND GET
SPENDING CUTS, THEY WANT A
MILLION DOLLAR CUT OFF FOR THE
TAXES TO INCREASE.
THAT SEEMS LIKE SOMETHING THAT
MIGHT BE PALATABLE ON THE
REPUBLICAN SIDE.
WE REALLY DON'T KNOW IN TERMS OF
THE LARGER REPUBLICAN HOUSE VOTE
WHETHER OR NOT JOHN BOEHNER
COULD GET THOSE VOTES BECAUSE
THERE ARE FOLKS IN THE HOUSE WHO
WANT TO SEE ABSOLUTELY NO TAX
INCREASES ON ANYBODY AS PART OF
THIS DEAL.
SO IT IS QUITE ABREU THAT WE ARE
WORKING ON HERE, AND BOB CORKER
MAKES SIGNIFICANT POINTS FOR THE
REPUBLICAN SIDE IN TERMS OF
DOING SOMETHING THAT REALLY
CREATES REFORM, THAT CHANGES THE
SYSTEM, THAT WORKS ON MEDICARE,
THAT WORKS ON SOCIAL SECURITY IN
A WAY THAT WILL START TO IMPROVE
OUR FISCAL SITUATION DOWN THE
ROAD AND MIGHT GET US OUT OF THE
WHOLE LONGER TERM.
THAT IS WHAT SEEMS TO BE MISSING
HERE.
BILL: IT'S DECEMBER 18th ON
THE CALENDAR.
WE KNEW MONTHS AGO AT SOME POINT
WE WERE GOING TO REACH CRUNCH
TIME.
I DON'T THINK WE ARE AT THAT
POINT YET.
YOU CAN FEEL THE GEARS WORKING
IN THAT DIRECTION AS OF TODAY,
BECAUSE --
MARTHA: I THINK PEOPLE ARE SO
FED UP WITH THIS PROCESS OF
HAVING TO TAKE EVERYTHING TO THE
LAST MINUTE TO GET IT DONE.
THEN WHAT HAPPENS IS, AND BOB
BECKEL SAID IT EARLIER, WELL
THERE IS JUST NO TIME RIGHT NOW
TO DO TAX REFORM, THERE IS NO
TIME TO DO ENTITLEMENT REFORMS,
AND AMERICANS ARE TOLD TIME AND
TIME AGAIN THAT THEY ARE OUT OF
TIME.
THEN YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENS,
BEFORE YOU KNOW IT YOU'RE TOO
CLOSE TO THE NEXT ELECTION TO
GET ANYTHING DONE, AND I JUST
THINK THE FRUSTRATION LEVEL IS
SO HUGE RIGHT NOW WITH ALL OF
THIS.
BILL: IF YOU PICK UP THE LINES
OUT OF WASHINGTON SOME OF THE
DEALS THAT THEY HAVE BEEN
TALKING ABOUT OVER THE PAST
COUPLE OF DAYS WOULD SAVE THE
COUNTRY $2 TRILLION OVER A
PERIOD OF TEN YEARS, WHICH I
MEAN $2 TRILLION, THAT IS A
MASSIVE AMOUNT OF MONEY.
BUT YET WHEN THE NATIONAL DEBT
STANDS AT 16.3 TRILLION NOW AND
IT'S STEADILY INCREASING AND
GOES UP HIGHER POSSIBLY TO
$20 TRILLION THREE OR FOUR YEARS
AGO, WHAT DOES $2 TRILLION TEN
YEARS AGO GET YOU?
THAT'S WHAT MOVES CORKER AROUND
TO HIS BIG IDEA, ABOUT DO 4,
4 1/2, $5 TRILLION, TO A GRAND
BARGAIN TO REDUCE THE SPENDING
AND THE SPENDING THAT WE HAVE
WATCHED GO UP INCREASINGLY BY
THE MINUTE IN WASHINGTON.
MARTHA: WE ARE GETTING
INFORMATION FROM OUR PRODUCER ON
THE HILL.
BASICALLY HE'S HIGHLIGHTING WHAT
I JUST MENTIONED A MOMENT AGO.
WE DON'T REALLY KNOW WHAT IS
GOING TO HAPPEN ON THE HOUSE
REPUBLICAN SIDE EVEN.
YOU DON'T KNOW HOW DIFFICULT
THEY MAY BE HAVING AT RALLYING
THE TROOPS IN TERMS OF EVEN A
MILLION DOLLAR LEVEL FOR
INCREASES ON TAXES BECAUSE THERE
WILL BE, YOU KNOW, ALL OF THOSE
TEA TEA PARTY REPUBLICANS AND
THOSE HE COMMITTED TO NOT
INCREASING TAXES AT ALL WILL
THEY PUT AT RISK THEIR
RE-ELECTION.
LINDSEY GRAHAM SAID THE REAL
ISSUE WILL BE THE DEBT CEILING,
BECAUSE AS WE KNOW THE PRESIDENT
WANTS A HANDS-OFF APPROACH TO
THE DEBT CEILING.
THEY WANT TO BE ABLE TO RAISE IT
WHENEVER THEY THINK IT'S
NECESSARY.
WE'VE HEARD TIMOTHY GEITHNER
TALK IN GREAT DETAIL ABOUT HOW
WE CAN'T RISK THE CREDIBILITY OF
THE U.S. DOLLAR, THE U.S.
ECONOMY, THE FINANCIAL SYSTEM
AND HAVING THOSE DOWNGRADES COME
IF WE DON'T RAISE THE DEBT
LIMIT.
A LOT OF FOLKS ARE SAYING HOW
CAN WE POSSIBLY ALLOW A
LIMITLESS CREDIT CARD FOR THE
UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT WITHOUT
ANY CHECK ON THAT.
A MAJOR ISSUE OF CONTENTION HERE
AS WELL.
BOB CORKER -- I'M SURE HE IS
RIGHT, THEY MAY BE VERY FAR
APART ONCOMING TO ANY CONCLUSION
AT ALL.
BILL: SPEAKER BOEHNER HAS MET
WITH MEMBERS OF HIS PARTY.
WE SHOULD SEE HIM IN A MATTER OF
MOMENTS.
LET'S TAKE A QUICK BREAK HERE,
WE'LL BRING THIS TO YOU AFTER A
COMMERCIAL AT TIME OUT.
I ALWAYS WAIT
UNTIL THE LAST MINUTE.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME R CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
MARTHA: WE ARE BACK AND WE ARE
WAITING FOR JOHN BOEHNER TO
SURFACE IN THAT ROOM AND TALK
ABOUT WHERE THIS IS GOING WITH
THE FISCAL CLIFF NEGOTIATIONS.
STEVE HAYES IS WITH ME NOW WITH
"THE WEEKLY STANDARD" AND FOX
NEWS CONTRIBUTOR.
HOW IS THIS GOING.
>> I THINK OUR FOCUSED ON
EXACTLY THE RIGHT QUESTION.
WHAT DID SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER
SAY TO HIS CONFERENCE THAT WOULD
ALLOW HIS PEOPLE TO ACCEPT SOME
KIND OF A GRAND BARGAIN WHICH
SEEMS TO BE WHAT HE WOULD PREFER
AT THIS POINT.
THERE IS DEEP SKEPTICISM AMONG
THE CONSERVATIVES IN THE HOUSE
OF REPRESENTATIVES WHO SAY WE
ARE NOT VOTING FOR TAX INCREASES
NOT BECAUSE WE ARE BEING OBJECT
STA NAT, WE AGREE IN PRINCIPLE
IT'S NOT A GOOD IDEA TO RAISE
TAXES AND GOVERNMENT IS SPENDING
TOO MUCH, THAT IS THE BIG
PROBLEM.
>> WHEN YOU LOOK AT THE DEAL IN
TERMS .
OUTLINE THAT WE ARE GETTING OF
IT, NO INCREASE IN THE MEDICARE
AGE WHICH MANY PEOPLE THINK IS
REASONABLE, NOT TO RAISE IT
RIGHT NOW BUT DOWN THE ROAD
WHICH ECHOES THE PAUL RYAN PLAN
AS ONE OF HIS ELEMENTS, RAISE
THE RATE FOR FOLKS UNDER 55
RIGHT NOW, NOT EVEN A COMPROMISE
ON THAT YET, STEVE.
>> I THINK THIS IS THE
FUNDAMENTAL PROBLEM.
WHATEVER WE SEE COME OUT OF
THESE FISCAL CLIFF NEGOTIATIONS
IT'S ALMOST CERTAIN NOT TO GET
TO THE HEART OF THE REAL
PROBLEM.
THE DRIVERS OF OUR DEBT ARE
ENTITLEMENTS, WE ARE TALKING
ABOUT SPENDING 60% OF OUR BUDGET
ON ENTITLEMENTS ON A HANDFUL OF
PROGRAMS THAT ARE -- THAT THE
SPENDING IS AUTOMATIC.
WE DON'T CONTROL IT FROM YEAR TO
YEAR.
UNLESS YOU DRAMATICALLY REFORM
THOSE PROGRAMS YOU'RE NOT GOING
TO GET IN FRONT OF THE DEBT
PROBLEM THAT THE COUNTRY FACES.
YOU'RE CERTAINLY NOT GOING TO
CHANGE THE TRAJECTORY OF THE
U.S. NATIONAL DEBT.
AND UNLESS AND UNTIL YOU DO THAT
ALL YOU'RE DOING IS SORT OF
MEDDLING AT THE MARGINS.
MARTHA: THIS SORT OF DISTASTE ON
THE DEMOCRAT'S SIDE FOR TAKE ON
THIS ISSUE IN ANY MEANINGFUL
WAY, I JUST WONDER, YOU KNOW, DO
THEY LOOK AT IT AND SAY, WELL,
NOW, IT WON US A PRESIDEN
PRESIDENTIAL ELECTION PROMISING
WE WON'T TOUCH ANY
ENTITLEMENTS.
BUT WHERE IS THE FOR SIGHT,
LOOKING DOWN THE ROAD?
I THINK PEOPLE ARE SO
DISTRUSTFUL NOW OF CONGRESS'
ABILITY TO GET ANYTHING DONE
THAT WILL CHANGE THE COURSE OF
WHERE WE ARE HEADED IN THIS
COUNTRY LONG TERM.
>> YEAH THEY SHOULD BE
DISTRUSTFUL.
THAT IS PART OF THE PROBLEM IS
THAT CONGRESS REFUSES TO TAKE
THESE ISSUES SERIOUSLY.
IT'S NOT JUST CONGRESS.
REMEMBER, PRESIDENT OBAMA IS THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
AND HE RAN THE FIRST TIME SAYING
THAT HE WAS GOING TO GET IN
FRONT OF THESE ISSUES THAT HE
WAS GOING --
MARTHA: LINE-BY-LINE HE WAS
GOING TO GO THROUGH EVERY SINGLE
PROGRAM.
>> EXACTLY.
IF YOU LOOK AT THE COMMENTS HE
MADE IN THE VERY FIRST MONTH OF
HIS PRESIDENCY BACK IN 2009 HE
SAID THAT THE CENTRAL PARK TO
GETTING IN FRONT OF THE U.S.
SPENDING PROBLEM IS GOING TO BE
TACKLING ENTITLEMENTS.
AND HE HASN'T DONE THAT.
THE ONLY INDICATIONS THAT HE'S
GIVEN AT ALL THAT HE WAS WILLING
TO CONTEMPLATE THIS CAME IN THE
CONTEXT OF THE DEBT CEILING
NEGOTIATIONS AND EVEN THOSE THE
WHITE HOUSE REFUSED REPEATEDLY
TO PUT ON PAPER, TO BE SPECIFIC
ABOUT.
SO HE HASN'T BEEN SERIOUS ABOUT
THIS.
AND I THINK FUNDAMENTALLY THIS
IS A PROBLEM OF LEADERSHIP AT
THE PRESIDENTIAL LEVEL.
MARTHA: ALL RIGHT.
THEY ARE COMING OUT NOW, STEVE.
THANKS A LOT.
LET'S LISTEN TO THIS AND GET
YOUR THOUGHTS ON IT LATER.
>> GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE.
OUR HOPE CONTINUES TO BE TO
REACH AN AGREEMENT WITH THE
PRESIDENT ON A BALANCED APPROACH
THAT AVERTS THE FISCAL CLIFF.
WHAT WE'VE OFFERED MEETS THE
DEFINITION OF BALANCE, BUT THE
PRESIDENT IS NOT THERE YET.
THE WHITE HOUSE OFFERED
YESTERDAY ESSENTIALLY A
$1.3 TRILLION IN NEW REVENUES
FOR ONLY $850 BILLION IN NET
SPENDING REDUCTIONS.
THAT IS NOT BALANCED IN MY
OPINION.
SO AT THE SAME TIME WE ARE GOING
TO CONTINUE TO TALK WITH THE
PRESIDENT, WE ARE GOING TO ALSO
MOVE PLAN B.
I THINK WE ALL KNOW THAT EVERY
INCOME TAX FILER IN AMERICA IS
GOING TO PAY HIGHER RATES COME
JANUARY THE 1st UNLESS
CONGRESS ACTS.
SO I BELIEVE IT'S IMPORTANT THAT
WE PROTECT AS MANY AMERICAN
TAXPAYERS AS WE CAN.
AND OUR PLAN B WOULD PROTECT
AMERICAN TAXPAYERS WHO MAKE A
MILLION DOLLARS OR LESS AND HAVE
ALL OF THEIR CURRENT RATES
EXTENDED.
I CONTINUE TO HAVE HOPE THAT WE
CAN REACH A BROADER AGREEMENT
WITH THE WHITE HOUSE THAT WOULD
REDUCE SPENDING AS WELL AS HAVE
REVENUES ON THE TABLE.
I THINK IT WOULD BE BETTER FOR
OUR COUNTRY, BUT AT THIS POINT
HAVING A BACK UP PLAN TO MAKE
SURE THAT AS FEW AMERICAN
TAXPAYERS ARE AFFECTED BY THIS
INCREASE AS POSSIBLE, MOVING
DOWN THAT PATH IS THE RIGHT
COURSE OF ACTION FOR US.
>> GOOD MORNING.
FIRST OF ALL I'D LIKE TO SAY
THAT I THINK ALL OF OUR HEARTS
AND PRAYERS ARE WITH THE
FAMILIES IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
AS A FATHER I CANNOT EVEN
IMAGINE THE UTTER HORROR THAT
THOSE FAMILIES ARE GOING THROUGH
RIGHT NOW GRIEVING THE LOSS OF
THEIR CHILDREN AND THEIR LOVED
ONES.
AS FAR AS THE FISCAL CLIFF IS
CONCERNED AS THE SPEAKER SAID WE
REMAIN COMMITTED TO TRYING TO
MINIMIZE THE IMPACT ON
HARD-WORKING FAMILIES AND SMALL
BUSINESSES IN THIS COUNTRY, AS
FAR AS TAX INCREASES ARE
CONCERNED.
WE LOOK TO FIND THE ANSWER TO
SOLVE THE PROBLEM ON THE
SPENDING ISSUE HERE IN
WASHINGTON.
THE PRESIDENT IS NOT YET THERE,
HE HAS NOT COME TO WHERE HE
NEEDS TO BE IN ORDER FOR US TO
PUSH THROUGH A BILL THAT REALLY
DOES BEGIN TO ADDRESS THE
PROBLEM.
AND AS THE SPEAKER SAID, THAT'S
WHY WE ARE NOW DISCUSSING AND
ALTERNATIVE PLAN IF THE
PRESIDENT AND THE WHITE HOUSE
CANNOT COME OUR WAY.
THANK YOU.
>> AS THE SPEAKER AND THE LEADER
SAID, WE'VE BEEN TRYING TO MAKE
SURE WE DO NOT GO OFF THIS
FISCAL CLIFF.
WHILE AT THE SAME TIME PUT
AMERICA ON A DIFFERENT PATH, ONE
FOR JOB CREATION, ONE THAT ALSO
TAKES CARE OF OUR SPENDING.
I THINK MANY TIMES THE SPEAKER
FELT THAT MAYBE HE WAS
NEGOTIATING WITH HIMSELF.
AFTER PLAN, AFTER PLAN WHERE THE
PRESIDENT STAYED SILENT.
THOSE THREE WEEKS RIGHT AFTER
THE ELECTION WHEN THE FIRST IDEA
WAS SENT ACROSS FROM THE
PRESIDENT TO THE SPEAKER WE
HEARD NOTHING BUT SILENCE.
UNFORTUNATELY TODAY WE ARE GOING
TO HAVE TO GO TO PLAN B.
BECAUSE WE WANT TO MAKE SURE WE
DO NOT GO OFF THE CLIFF AND WE
WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT WE KEEP
AN ECONOMY WHERE JOBS CAN BE
CREATED.
BUT THE THING WE HAVE TO
REMEMBER IS WHERE WE ARE IN THE
SITUATION.
WE ARE TWO MONTHS INTO A NEW
FISCAL YEAR.
WE SHOULD ALWAYS LOOK AT THE
NUMBERS, BECAUSE THEY CAN TELL
YOU IN A SCENARIO WHERE WE ARE.
IN TWO MONTHS WE ARE
$292 BILLION IN DEBT.
WHEN YOU READ THE NUMBERS THERE
IS SOME POSITIVE NEWS IN IT,
REVENUES ARE UP BY 10%,
$30 BILLION.
THAT IS 1 BILLION LESS THAN
YOU'D GET IF YOU JUST RAISED THE
TOP TWO RATES FOR THE FIRST
YEAR.
BUT THE SAD REALITY IS SPENDING
IS UP 16%.
$87BILLION.
THAT IS WHERE THE PROBLEM LIES,
THAT'S WHERE THE PRESIDENT HAS
TO START TALKING ABOUT AND
THAT'S WHAT WE WANT TO SOLVE IN
THE LONG RUN.
AN AMERICA FOR THE CHILDREN AND
THE FUTURE THAT WE CAN BUILD AND
ONE THAT CAN CREATE JOBS.
MARTHA: THAT IS THE MAJORITY
WHIP KEVIN MCCARTHY SAYING WE
ARE TAKING IN MORE REVENUE, THAT
IS GOOD NEWS BUT WE ARE SPENDING
WAY OUT PACING WHAT WE ARE
TAKING IN AGAIN IN THE NEW
FISCAL YEAR AND HE'S QUESTIONING
WHAT THE WHITE HOUSE WOULD LIKE
TO DO ABOUT THAT SITUATION GOING
DOWN THE ROAD, SO NOWHERE IS
WHERE WE APPEAR TO BE ON THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
THEY WILL TRY TO GET A VOTE
THROUGH ON THE REPUBLICAN SIDE
WITH THIS PLAN B ISSUE.
AND WE'LL TELL YOU WHERE THAT IS
GOING TO TAKE US.
BILL: IT LOOKS LIKE THE
REPUBLICANS ARE RETURNING
SERVE.
MARTHA: YES.
BILL: WE'LL SEE WHAT THE WHITE
HOUSE DOES NEXT.
DECEMBER 18th, FOLKS ON THE
CALENDAR.
THERE IS NEW EVIDENCE ABOUT THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING MASSACRE BUT AS
POLICE CONTINUE THAT
INVESTIGATION THEY ARE NOT SO
CERTAIN IT WILL DO MUCH GOOD.
WE'LL EXPLAIN WHAT IS HAPPENING
WITH THAT IN A MOMENT.
MARTHA: ABG A LOOK AT THIS.
THE FIRST PICTURE OF A FORMER
U.S. MARINE LOCKED INSIDE A
MEXICAN PRISON.
WHY HIS MOTHER SAYS HE CAN'T
COME HOME SOON ENOUGH.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH MORE IN
"AMERICA'S NEWSROOM."
I LOVE THE HOLIDAYS.
AND WITH MY BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CREDIT CARD,
I LOVE 'EM EVEN MORE.
I EARN 1% CASH BACK EVERYWHERE,
EVERTIME.
2% ON GROCERIES.
3% ON GAS.
AUTOMATICALLY.
NO HOOPS TO JUMP THROUGH.
THAT'S 1% BACK ON...
[ toy robot sounds ]
2% ON PUMPN PIE.
AND APPLE.
3% BACK ON 4 TRIPS
TO THE AIRPORT.
IT'S AS EASY AS..
-[ man ] 1...
-[ woman ] 2...
[ woman ] 3.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CARD.
APPLY ONLINE OR AT
A BANK OF AMERICA NEAR YOU.
BILL: WE ARE HEARING FROM
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE SAYING
THEY HAVE VERY GOOD EVIDENCE,
THAT ACE QUOTE NOW THAT COULD
ANSWER QUESTIONS ABOUT ADAM
LANZA'S MOTIVE.
HE DID NOT MAKE IT EASY FOR
INVESTIGATORS.
THERE ARE SEVERAL REPORTS
UNCONFIRMED BUT THERE ARE
REPORTS THAT HE REMOVED HIS
COMPUTER'S HARD DRIVE DISK AND
SMASHED IT TO PIECES.
BUT POLICE WILL NOT STOP UNTIL
THEY HAVE THE ANSWERS TO THAT.
>> WE GOING TO DO EVERYTHING
THAT IT TAKES TO INSUR INCH
EVEN SURINSURE WE GET ALL THE
EVIDENCE AND CONDUCT INTERVIEWS
TO PAINT A CLEAR PICTURE AS TO
EXACTLY HOW AND WHY THIS TRAGEDY
OCCURRED.
>> RON WHAOERL IS A FORMER D.C.
HOMICIDE DETECTIVE.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
YOU PUT A SERIES OF THOUGHTS
TOEGT THAT CREATE ONE THEORY.
GO AHEAD, EXPLAIN THAT AND THEN
WE'LL TALK ABOUT THAT.
>> FIRST OF ALL WE ARE DEALING
WITH A PERSON AS EVERYBODY HAS
BEEN SAYING THAT IS POSSIBLY
MENTALLY ILL.
NOT ONLY IS HE POSSIBLY MENTALLY
ILL HE'S A VERY COLD AND
CALCULATED KILLER.
LET'S LOOK AT SOME OF THE
EVIDENCE THAT WE'VE HEARD ABOUT
ALREADY, BILL REAL QUICKLY THE
POLICE HAVE SAID THAT THEY HAVE
VERY GOOD EVIDENCE.
WHAT COULD THAT VERY GOOD
EVIDENCE BE?
WHAT I THINK IT IS, I THINK ON
THAT COMPUTER HARD DRIVE WHAT
THEY WILL FIND ONCE THEY ARE
ABLE TO GET INTO IT IS THAT THIS
GUY HAD BEEN RESEARCHING A LOT
OF THE ACTIVITY SURROUNDING THE
AURORA, COLORADO SHOOTING AND
SPECIFICALLY THE MINDSET OF
JAMES HOLMES WHO WAS THE SHOOTER
WHO HAD A VERY SIMILAR MINDSET
TO THIS GUY LANZA LAST WEEK.
BILL: ARE YOU SAYING THAT, OR DO
YOU HAVE THAT ON AUTHORITY?
>> NO, NO, NO --
BILL: THAT IS YOUR THEORY.
>> THIS IS WHAT I BELIEVE.
THIS IS JUST A THEORY.
THIS IS WHAT I BELIEVE.
IF YOU LOOK AT BOTH OF THESE
INDIVIDUALS AND THEIR MINDSETS
THEY ARE VERY SIMILAR.
NOW WHY THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
BILL?
THAT IS A QUESTION THAT
EVERYBODY HAS BEEN ASKING.
NOW JUST YESTERDAY THE POLICE
DEPARTMENT SAID THERE WAS NO
CONNECTION BETWEEN LANZA AND THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, BUT HERE IS
THE CORRELATION RIGHT HERE.
WHERE WILL YOU FIND A LARGE
NUMBER OF CHILDREN TOGETHER ON A
FRIDAY MORNING?
AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
HOW DO YOU AFFECT THE FABRIC,
THE CORE OF THIS NATION
ESPECIALLY THE ADULTS, YOU
ATTACK THE CHILDREN.
THAT IS THE SAME MINDSET, BILL
THAT THE COLORADO SHOOTER HAD.
BILL: NOW HOLD ON NOW, OKAY.
HIS HOME IS APPARENTLY TEN MILES
FROM THE SCHOOL.
THERE ARE OTHER SCHOOLS ALONG
THAT ROAD THAT YOU KNOW OF.
>> RIGHT.
BILL: THEY HAVE SAID THAT ADAM
LANZA HAS NO CONNECTION TO THE
SCHOOL.
THEY HAVE NOT DEFINED WHAT THE
MOTHER'S RELATIONSHIP WAS.
REMEMBERER EARLY ON WE THOUGHT
TWAUSZ  SHE WAS A TEACHER.
TWO SOURCES CLOSE TO THE POLICE
DEPARTMENT SAID SHE VOLUNTEERED
AT THE SCHOOL.
I TALKED TO POLICE IN
CONNECTICUT AS WELL AND I ASKED
ABOUT THE HARD DRIVE.
THEY WOULD NOT CONFIRM ANY OF
THIS INFORMATION THAT IS BEING
REPORTED TODAY.
>> RIGHT.
BUT YOU KNOW, HE WAS FAMILIAR, I
THINK, BILL, AND YOU MAY KNOW
FROM BEING UP THERE THE PAST
COUPLE OF DAYS, BUT IT'S BEEN
REPORTED THAT HE WAS FAMILIAR
WITH THAT SCHOOL.
HE WAS FAMILIAR WITH THAT AREA,
AND TYPICALLY, BILL, IN A
SITUATION LIKE THIS THE SHOOTER,
ESPECIALLY AN ACTIVE SHOOTER
WILL GO TO A PLACE THAT THEY ARE
SOMEWHAT FAMILIAR W. WHY?
BECAUSE THEY ARE GOING TO TRY TO
PLAN THEIR ESCAPE AT THE SAME
TIME.
I THINK ALL OF THESE FACETS,
ONCE THEY COME TOGETHER, WE
GOING TO SEE A STRIKING
SIMILARITY TO THE AURORA
COLORADO SHOOTER.
BILL: WE WILL WATCH ALL THAT AND
SEE IF YOUR THEORY PANS OUT.
AS FOR THIS COMPUTER WE DON'T
KNOW IF IT WAS HIS OR HIS
MOTHER'S.
WE DON'T KNOW IN THE END IF IT
WAS TRULY SMASHED UP OR IF IT
WERE HOW MUCH OF IT WAS
DESTROYED.
WE ARE WAITING FOR A LOT OF THIS
STUFF AS YOU KNOW.
ANSWERS ARE ILLUSIVE.
THANK YOU, ROD WHEELER TRYING TO
PIECE THIS TOGETHER AS ARE SO
MANY MILLIONS OF US.
THANK YOU.
MARTHA: THE LATEST ON THE MARINE
VETERAN WHO IS LOOKED UP IN
MEXICO.
CAN ANYTHING BE DONE TO BRING
THIS YOUNG MAN, JOHN HAMMER, WHO
IS CHAINED TO THAT BED IN
MEXICO, BRING HIM HOME?
DOES HIS MILITARY STATUS HAVE
ANYTHING TO DO WITH WHY HE'S
BEING HELD THAT WAY?
>> I DIDN'T OPEN THAT LETTER
UNTIL THIS MORNING.
THEY SPECIFICALLY STATE THAT HE
IS BEING CHAINED BECAUSE OF HIS
MILITARY EXPERIENCE.
SO FOR THE PEOPLE THAT HAVE BEEN
ASKING ME, YOU KNOW, WHY DO YOU
THINK HE'S CHAINED, AND NOW WE
KNOW.
MARTHA: FOX NEWS ALERT AS
AMERICA GETS ITS FIRST LOOK AT A
FORMER MARINAS HE SITS LOCKED UP
IN A MEXICAN PRISON, SHIRTLESS
AND CHAINED TO THE BED POST OVER
WHAT LAWYERS SAY IS A TRUMPED UP
CHARGE OF CARRYING A SUPPOSEDLY
ILLEGAL SHOTGUN OVER THE U.S.
BORDER INTO MEXICO.
JOHN HAMMER APPEARS TO BE
UNHARMED IN THIS IMAGE, BUT THE
CONDITIONS THAT HE'S BEING HELD
IN ARE WHAT IS WORRYING HIS
FAMILY.
AND WHEN HIS MOTHER WAS ASKED
ABOUT HOW THIS PHOTO MADE HER
FEEL WHEN SHE SAW IT EARLIER
TODAY, SHE SAID THE EMOTIONS FOR
HER ARE SIMPLY TOO MUCH TO
BEAR.
>> I'M SHATTERED.
I WAS JUST SHATTERED.
HE LOOKS -- HE LOOKS SO
HOPELESS, AND, YOU KNOW, AS A
MOTHER TO SEE YOUR CHILD LOOK
LIKE THAT, AND NOT BE ABLE TO
HELP THEM IS JUST -- IT FEELS
OBSCENE.
MARTHA: I CAN JUST IMAGINE HOW
SHE FEELS.
ERIC SHAWN IS HERE WITH US HERE
IN NEW YORK ON THE BACKGROUND ON
THIS STORY.
GOOD MORNING, ERIC.
>> HE SERVED IN IRAQ AND
TKPW-PBZ AND NO AFGHANISTAN AND
YOU CAN SEE FORMER U.S. MARINE
JOHN HAMMER IS LOCKED IN
SOLITARY CONFINEMENT IN A
MEXICAN PRISON CHAINED BY HIS
FOOT TO A BED OVER WHAT HIS
FAMILY CALLS A CLERICAL ERROR.
THEY WERE ON THE WAY TO HUNT AND
SURF IN COSTA RICA.
WHEN THEY ARRIVED IN MEXICO THEY
WERE ARRESTED FOR BRINGING IN AN
ILLEGAL WEAPON, A GUN HIS MOTHER
SAYS IS AN ANTIQUE THAT BELONGED
TO THIS IS GREAT GRANDFATHER AND
TRIED TO REPBL REGISTER.
MEXICAN AUTHORITIES SAID THE
BARREL WAS TOO SHORT UNDER THE
LEGAL LIMITS THERE.
HIS MOTHER TOLD FOX & FRIENDS
THIS MORNING IT'S ALL AN
ADMINISTRATIVE MISTAKE.
>> JOHNNY MADE AN ADMINISTRATIVE
MISTAKE, HE SHOULD HAVE
REGISTERED THE GUN AT AN EMBASSY
IN THE UNITED STATES BEFORE
GOING OVER THERE.
BASICALLY HE HAS BEEN IN JAIL
FOR FOUR MONTHS, CHAINED TO A
BED OVER A CLERICAL ERROR.
>> SHE DOES NOT HOLDOUT HOPE
THAT JOHN WILL BE HOME BY
CHRISTMAS BECAUSE HIS NEXT COURT
DATE DOESN'T COME UNTIL THE
MIDDLE OF JANUARY, MARTHA.
MARTHA: WHAT IS THE MEXICAN
GOVERNMENT SAYING ABOUT THIS
CASE?
>> Reporter: THE MEXICAN
GOVERNMENT AND THE AMBASSADOR
SAYS ANTIQUE OR NOT IT'S
ILLINOIS LEGAL TOMORROW PORT
GUNS INTO THE COUNTRY.
THAT'S WHY JOHN WAS ARRESTED.
THERE IS A LETTER FROM THE U.S.
AMBASSADOR SAYING THE FACT THAT
THIS CASE HAS BEEN THIS PROCESS
SINCE AUGUST IS NORMAL.
GIVEN THE NATURE OF THE FELONY
HE WAS DETAINED FOR.
INTRODUCING OR PRODUCING WEAPONS
OF THIS KIND IN MEXICO REGARD
LEAFS INTENT IS ILLEGAL AND
CONSIDERED A SERIOUS OFFENSE.
THE STATE DEPARTMENT ALSO SAYS
AMERICANS ARE ARRESTED IN
MEXICO'S EVERY YEAR FOR
VIOLATING THE COUNTRY'S GUN
LAWS.
A DISABLED VETERAN HAS STARTED
AN ONLINE FACEBOOK, FREE JOHN
HAMMER.
IF HE IS NOT FREE HE FACES 12
MORE YEARS IN A MEXICAN PRISON
IF CONVICTED.
MARTHA: JUST IMAGINE WHAT HIS
FAMILY IS GOING THROUGH, ERIC.
THANK YOU FOR THE BACKGROUND ON
ALL OF THAT.
HERE WITH MORE ON THIS CASE.
KULLY SIMPSON IS A FORMER
SECRETARY OF DEFENSE, A SENIOR
LEGAL FELLOW AT THE HERITAGE
FOUNDATION AND WE THANK HIM FOR
JOINING US.
AND APOLLIO ACOSTA IS A FORMER
DIRECTOR IN THE EMBASSY IN
MEXICO CITY.
APOLLO, DO YOU AGREE THERE IS
ANYWAY HE CAN BE HOME FOR
CHRISTMAS?
>> I DON'T SEE THAT HE'LL BE
HOME FOR CHRISTMAS AT ALL.
I THINK, YOU KNOW, THE EARLIER
REPORTS -- HIS NEXT HEARING IS
IN MID JANUARY AND I DON'T
EXPECT ANY ACTION TO BE TAKEN
UNTIL THEN.
MARTHA: WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF THIS
CASE, KULLY?
>> IT'S A TRAGEDY.
MARTHA: LET'S GO TO KULLY
FIRST.
>> THANKS, MARTHA IT'S A
TRAGEDY.
FROM WHAT I'VE READ HE ACTUALLY
TRIED TO SPEAK WITH U.S. CUSTOM
AND BORDER PATROL AGENTS BEFORE
HE CROSSED THE MEXICAN BORDER TO
MAKE SURE IT WAS OKAY TO BRING
THIS 24-INCH, 410 SHOTGUN
TRANSIT THROUGH MEXICO TO GO
SURFING DOWN IN COSTA RICA, HE
CLEARLY HAD NO ILL INTENT.
I AGREE WITH MY COGUEST THAT IT
DOESN'T LOOK LIKE THERE WILL BE
ANY ACTION EXCEPT FOR THE COURT
ACTION IN JANUARY.
THE ADMINISTRATION NEEDS TO DO
MORE QUIETLY BEHIND THE SCENES
TO MAKE SURE HE'S PROVIDED THE
COUNSELOR SERVICES HE DESERVES
AND HAS A RIGHT TO HAVE
ESPECIALLY AS A COMBAT DECORATED
MARINE.
MARTHA: IS IT TYPICAL FOR THIS
KIND OF VIOLATION TO GARNER THIS
KIND OF PRISON SENTENCE AND THIS
KIND OF TREATMENT.
HE'S SHIRTLESS AND KHEUPBD TO A
BED, REALLY?
FOR BRINGING AN UNREGISTERED GUN
ACROSS THE BORDER?
LOOK AT FAST AND FURIOUS WE'VE
SEEN GUNS FLY ACROSS THIS BORDER
AND NOBODY SEEMS TO PAY THE
PRICE EXCEPT FOR SOME PEOPLE
THAT LOST THEIR LIVES IN THAT
TRANSACTION.
>> LET'S BE CLEAR THE CONDITIONS
IN MEXICAN JAILS ARE
DEPLORABLE.
THEY ADDRESS THE EUPL PROCEDUR
THE IMPORTATION OF WEAPONS AS
DESCRIBED BY THE AMBASSADOR.
THE INTENTION OF THIS AMERICAN
WAS NOT TO VIOLATE MEXICAN
IMMIGRATION LAW.
WHAT I FIND EVEN MORE DEPLORABLE
IS THAT THE MEXICAN GOVERNMENT
WILL BE VERY -- VERY HARSH ON
ANY TREATMENT OF THEIR MEXICAN
CITIZENS EVEN IF THEY ENTER THE
COUNTRY ILLEGALLY AND VIOLATE
THE LAW WITHIN TENSION.
IN THIS PARTICULAR CASE IT GOES
TO SAY THAT THERE WAS NO INTENT
ON MR. HAMMER TO VIOLATE THE LAW
AS HE ENTERED MEXICO, HE TRIED
TO DECLARE THE WEAPON.
YET I WILL TELL YOU THAT MEXICAN
PROSECUTORS WILL NOT BACK OFF
REGARDLESS OF WHAT THE INTENT OF
MR. HAMMER WAS.
MARTHA: ALL RIGHT.
SO YOU LOOK FOR A WAY TO DEAL
WITH THIS PROBLEM IN WASHINGTON,
DIPLOMATICALLY BEHIND CLOSED
DOORS SO IT DOESN'T BECOME
SOMETHING THAT HA IS AN EPL BAR
A ASment TO THE MEXICAN
GOVERNMENT IF THEY APPEAR TO
BACK DOWN ON THE CHARGES AGAINST
THIS YOUNG MAN.
WHAT IS THE BEST WAY FOR HIS
FAMILY TO PURSUE THIS AND WHAT
DO YOU THINK IS THE BEST WAY FOR
THE THE GOVERNMENT TO HANDLE
IT?
STPHREU THINK TH
>> I THINK THE FAMILY IS DOING
THE RIGHT THING.
GET ON THE MEDIA, CONTACT THE
REPRESENTATIVES.
REPRESENTATIVES HAVE WRITTEN THE
SOAK OF STATE IN THE UNITED
STATES AND THE MEDIA NEEDS TO
KEEP ON THIS STORY.
IF THERE IS A PLEA IN JANUARY OR
SHORTLY THERE AFTER OR A
CONVICTION AFTER A TRIAL IT'S AT
THAT POINT WHEN HE'S SENTENCED
WHEN THE GOVERNMENT OF THE
UNITED STATES HAS THE MOST
LEVERAGE, THEY CAN SAY, LOOK YOU
GOT YOUR POUND OF FLESH, YOU
PROSECUTED HIM, THAT SENTENCE IS
WAY TOO LONG.
WE'LL TAKE CARE THE SITUATION
AND BRING HIM HOME.
JUSTICE IS SERVED, NOW IT'S TIME
TO BRING HIM HOME.
I THINK PRESSURE REALLY
MATTERSES ESPECIALLY BEHIND THE
SCENES.
IF THE U.S. GOVERNMENT REALLY
WANTED THIS GUY HOME THEY COULD
DO A LOT TO PRESSURE THE MEXICAN
GOVERNMENT BEHIND THE SCENES TO
MAKE IT HAPPEN SOME TIME IN
JANUARY.
MARTHA: WE'LL STAY ON IT.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US
TODAY.
BILL: A NIGHT OF HEAVY DRINKING
AND A 19-YEAR-OLD IS FOUND
DEAD.
NOW MEMBERS OF A COLLEGE
FRATERNITY ARE FACING CHARGES,
AND SOME OF THOSE CHARGES ARE
EVEN FELONIES.
>> HE WANTED TO BE LIKED.
HE WANTED TO BE ACCEPTED.
THE TERMS THAT THE FRATERNITY
PLACED ON HIM IS THAT HE HAD TO
GO THROUGH THIS.
>> HE HAD TO DRINK?
>> YES.
COPD makes it hard
to breathe,
but with ADVAIR,
I'm breathing better.
So now I can be in
the scene.
ADVAIR is
clinically proven to help
significantly improve
lung function.
Unlike most COPD medications,
ADVAIR contains both an
anti-inflammatory
and a
long-acting bronchodilator
working together to help improve
your lung function all day.
ADVAIR won't
replace fast-acting inhalers
for sudden symptoms
and should not be used more
than twice a day.
People with
COPD taking ADVAIR
may have a higher chance
of pneumonia.
ADVAIR may increase your
risk of osteoporosis
and some eye problems.
Tell your doctor
if you have a heart condition
or high blood pressure before
taking ADVAIR.
If you're still
having difficulty breathing,
ask your doctor if including
ADVAIR could help
improve your lung function.
Get your
first full
prescription
free
and save
on refills
at
ADVAIRcopd.com.
MARTHA: OUT OF THE SADNESS IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT WE ARE
LEARNING TODAY AN INCREDIBLE
STORY.
THIS MAN LIVES NEAR SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND HE'S
SPEAKING OUT ABOUT HIS
EXPERIENCE OF COMING HOME AND
FINDING SIX SMALL CHILDREN
SITTING IN A SEMI CIRCLE ON HIS
LAWN.
HE HAD HEARD THE GUNFIRE ON HIS
WAY BACK FROM BREAKFAST AT A
LOCAL DINER AND HE THOUGHT IT
WAS A HUNTER, THEN HE SAW THESE
CHILDREN SITTING ON HIS FRONT
LAWN.
HE STARTED TO TALK TO THEM, GAVE
HIM JUICE AND TOYS AND THEY
RECOUNTED WHAT HAD HAPPENED .
LISTEN TO THIS.
>> OVER THE NEXT 30 MINUTES THEY
JUST DESCRIBED WHAT HAPPENED,
LITTLE BY LITTLE, AND THESE TWO
BOYS KEPT SAYING, WE CAN'T GO
BACK TO SCHOOL, WE CAN'T GO BACK
TO SCHOOL.
OUR TEACHER IS DEED.
MRS. SOTO, WE DON'T HAVE A
TEACHER.
AND I COULDN'T BELIEVE THAT.
I COULDN'T TAKE THAT IN.
I HAD NO IDEA WHAT HAD
HAPPENED.
MARTHA: SO, SO, SO SAD.
AND LISTENING TO HIS STORY, AND
HE SAID AT FIRST HE SAW THEM ON
THE LAWN I THOUGHT THEY WERE
PUTTING ON APPLY OR SOMETHING.
HE WAS TRYING TO UNDERSTAND WHAT
THEY COULD POSSIBLY BE DOING ON
HIS FRONT LAWN.
WE ALL KNOW HOW CHILDREN FEEL
ABOUT HIS TEACHER, IT IS THE
MOST IMPORTANT PERSON IN THEIR
LIFE OUTSIDE OF THEIR FAMILY.
YOUR HEART JUST BREAKS LISTENING
TO THE STORY.
SCHOOL HAS BEGUN AGAIN FOR OTHER
CHILDREN IN SANDY HOOK BUT NOT
THE CHILDREN THAT GO TO THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE CONTINUE TO BRING YOU THEIR
STORIES THROUGHOUT THE WEEK.
BILL: IT WILL BE A TOUGH DAY
THERE AGAIN TODAY WITH THE
PARENTS SENDING THEIR KID BACK
TO SCHOOL AND WONDERING IF THEY
ARE OKAY AND DROPPING THEM OFF
AND PICKING THEM UP AND ON IT
GOES FOR THEM, SORE SO MANY.
LET'S TURN OUR ATTENTION NOW,
ANOTHER ALLEGED HAZING INCIDENT
THAT HAS TURNED INTO DEADLY
RESULTS LEADING TO CHARGES
AGAINST MORE THAN 20 MEMBERS OF
A FRATERNITY.
THIS IS NORTHERN ILLINOIS
UNIVERSITY, FIVE FACE FELONY
CHARGES.
POLICE SAY 19-YEAR-OLD FRESHMAN
WAS FOUND DEAD IN THE FRATERNITY
HOUSE AFTER A NIGHT OF HEAVY
DRINKING, BLOOD/ALCOHOL LEVEL
FIVE TIMES THE LEGAL LIMIT IN
THAT YOUNG MAN.
>> YOU HAVE TO RUN A GAUNTLET OF
LIQUOR ON DOING WHATEVER IT IS
ALL THE GIRLS TELL YOU UNTIL YOU
FIND A GIRL THAT'S YOURS.
IT INVOLVES DRINKING ANYWHERE
FROM TWO TO FIVE SHOTS OF LIQUOR
PER GIRL.
>> A CRIMINAL DEFENSE ATTORNEY
IS LOOKING INTO THIS WITH ME.
THIS WAS A RITUAL CALLED
PARENTS' NIGHT?
>> GOOD MORNING.
BILL.
IT'S CRAZY WHAT THEY DID IS THE
JUNIORS AND SENIORS AT THE
FRATERNITY WOULD HAVE THE
FRESHMAN BEING HAZED GO ROOM TO
ROOM.
THEY WOULD BE ASKED QUESTIONS
AND EVERY TIME THEY WOULD ANSWER
A QUESTION THEY HAVE TO DO
ANOTHER SHOT.
THEY GO ROOM TO ROOM TO ROOM
DOING A SHOT, A SHOT, A SHOT, WE
CAN IMAGINE HOW MANY SHOTS HE
ACTUALLY DID.
THE FRATERNITY HAS 1010, 15, 20
ROOMS, WE ARE TALKING ABOUT THAT
MANY SHOTS.
SEVERAL OF THE FRESHMAN WERE
LEFT UNCONSCIOUS, ONE OF THEM
ACTUALLY DIED.
IT WAS A PRETTY HORRIFIC
EXPERIENCE.
FIVE FELONIES AND 17
MISDEMEANORS CAME OUT OF THIS.
BILL: A LOT OF TIMES YOU HEAR
ABOUT CHARGES ON THIS BUT NOT
FELONIES VERY OFTEN.
WHY THIS THIS CASE?
>> THE PENDULUM HAS ESSENTIALLY
SWUNG TOO FAR, LIKE IN THE LAST
CASE WE SAW THERE HAVE BEEN A
TREMENDOUS AMOUNT OF HAZING
PROBLEMS IN THIS COUNTRY.
TEXAS TEXAS A&M, YOUNGSTOWN,
YALE HAD ONE.
WHAT THEY ARE DOING NOW THE
LEGISLATE LATERS IF YOU WILL ARE
IN 45 OF THE 50 STATES ARE
COMING UP WITH FELONY CHARGES
WHERE IF THEY DON'T GET PRIOR
APPROVAL FOR THE INCIDENT AND IF
THEIR CONDUCT IS SO OUTRAGEOUS,
SO NEGLIGENT OR IN TENSION
ALTHERE ARE STATUTES ENACTED TO
ACTUALLY HOLD THE PEOPLE, MAKE
THEM ACCOUNTABLE FROM CORNELL
UNIVERSITY ALL THE WAY TO TEXAS
A&M.
BILL: IS THERE EVIDENCE OF
INTENT TO HARM DAVID?
HAVE YOU FOUND THAT YET?
>> THE ANSWER IS THERE IS
EVIDENCE OF INTENT TO HARM, NOT
TO KILL.
WELL INTENT TO GET THEM DRUNK
AND IT'S VIOLENTLY DRUNK.
YOU NEED NOT SHOW INTENT YOU CAN
SHOW A RECKLESSNESS.
A RECKLESS DISREGARD FOR MENTAL
OR PHYSICAL WELL-BEING THAT IS
ENOUGH UNDER THE FELONY STATUTES
IN MANY MUCH THE STATES.
BILL: IT IS ENOUGH.
>> IT IS.
AND THE LEGISLATURE
INTENTIONALLY MADE IT A LOWER
BURDEN, A LESSER OF A STANDARD
TO ESSENTIALLY STOP THAT
PENDULUM SWINGING.
YOU CAN'T HAVE THESE KIDS JUST
DOING 15, 20, 25 SHOTS IN A
NIGHT WITHOUT IT BEING HARMFUL
TO THEM.
BILL: IF IT IS PROVEN OUT, IT'S
BEEN REPORTED THAT DAVID
KNOWINGLY AND WILLINGLY TOOK
PART IN THIS DRINKING GAME.
THIS THAT HOLDS UP HOW DOES THAT
FACTOR INTO THESE CHARGES?
>> WELL, THERE IS IN PRACTICALLY
ALL THE STATES THERE IS NO SELF,
THERE IS NO DEFENSE, THERE IS NO
DEFENSE THAT I I
KNEW ABOUT IT BECAUSE ALL THESE
KIDS WANT TO GET IN A
FRATERNITY.
IT'S NOT APPLICABLE IN THESE
INSTANCES.
THEY COULD BE GOING TO JAIL
THESE KIDS.
BILL: WHAT WOULD BE THE PENALTY
THEN?
A FELONY IN A CASE LIKE THIS
COULD BE?
>> GENERALLY ONE TO THREE YEARS,
SOME MAYBE PROBATION.
IT COULD BE A GOOD YEAR IN JAIL
IF IN FACT THE PROSECUTORS GET
WHAT THEY WANT.
BILL: FOR A 120-YEAR-OLD
STUDENT.
>> ABSOLUTELY AND THROWN OUT OF
THE SCHOOL, ET CETERA.
BILL: A HIGH PRICE TO PAY.
WE'LL SEE HOW THIS UNTPOEPLDZ
HERE ANUNFOLDS HERE AND OUR
BEST TO THE FAMILY.
>> IT'S VERY SAD.
MARTHA: LET'S HEAD OVER TO JENNA
LEE AND FIND OUT WHAT SHE HAS
COMING UP.
JENNA: WE WILL HAVE CONTINUING
COVERAGE OUT OF NEWTOWN THE
LATEST DEVELOPMENTS OUT OF
CONNECTICUT.
WE'LL TAKE SOME OF OUR VIEWER
QUESTIONS ABOUT THE MEDIA
COVERAGE OF THIS EVENT AS WELL,
WHETHER THAT IS DOING MORE HARM
THAN GOOD.
WE'LL TACKLE THAT IN OUR NEWS
WATCH PANEL.
IRAN NOW SAYS OUR ACTIONS IN
SYRIA AND TURKEY ARE SETTING US
UP FOR A WORLD WAR.
THAT IS WHAT THEY SAY.
WHY?
IS THAT A CREDIBLE THREAT?
WE'LL TALK ABOUT THAT.
PLUS IT LOOKS LIKE A POSSIBLE
DEAL TO AVERT THE SO-CALLED
FISCAL CLIFF, WE'LL KEEP YOU
POSTED ON THE ACTIONS OUT OF
D.C.
ONE COMPANY OUT OF CALIFORNIA IS
ACTUALLY MAKING SOME MONEY OFF
OF THIS WHOLE FISCAL CLIFF
THING.
WE'LL TELL YOU HOW.
MARTHA: IT'S A GOOD TRICK.
JENNA THANKS A LOT.
IT IS A TRAINING FACILITY LIKE
NONE OTHER IN THE WORLD TRAINING
TENS OF THOUSANDS OF LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICERS TO STOP ANY
NUMBER OF THEY ARER THREAT THEY
THEY ARE OR THREATS BEFORE THEY
HAPPEN.
A GOOD IDEA, RIGHT?
WE'LL TAKE AN INSIDE LOOK AT THE
HIGHLY SECRETIVE OPERATION.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS DECEMBER, REMEMBER --
YOU CAN STAY IN
AND SHARE SOMETHING...
OR YOU CAN GET OUT THERE
AND ACTUALLY SHARE SOMETHING.
♪
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
BILL: TODAY WE REMEMBER HAWAII
SENATOR DANIEL INOYE HE DIED
YESTERDAY OF RESPIRATORY
COMPLICATIONS.
HE WAS 17 WHEN THE JAPANESE
ATTACKED PEARL HARBOR AND JOINED
THE MILITARY TWO YEARS LATER AND
RECEIVED THE MEDAL OF HONOR FOR
A BATTLE AGAINST THE GERMANS
WHERE HE WAS SEVERELY WOUNDED,
LOST AN ARM.
HE WAS A MEMBER OF HAWAII'S
FIRST CONGRESSIONAL DELEGATION
BEFORE WINNING A SENATE SEAT AND
SERVING FOR NEARLY 50 YEARS.
>> WE'LL ALL MISS HIM AND THAT
IS A GROSS UNDERSTATEMENT.
>> HE LIVED A REMARKABLE
AMERICAN LIFE FILLED WITH
DIGNITY AND GRACE OF THE TRUE
HERO THAT HE WAS.
BILL: IN 2009 HE BECOME THE
CHAIRMAN MUCH THE SENATE
APPROPRIATIONS COMMITTEE AND THE
PRESIDENT PRO TEM MAKING HIM
THIRD IN LINE FOR THE
PRESIDENCY.
DANIEL, NOUYE.
A SENATOR, 88 YEARS OLD.
MARTHAA ONE OF A KIND TRAINING
FACILITY FOR LAW ENFORCEMENT
WHERE OFFICERS TRAIN TO THREAT
ANY TERRORIST THREAT.
IT LOCATED IN BUNS WICK,
GEORGIA, AND THAT IS WHERE WE
FIND NONE OTHER THAN OF COURSE
STEVE HARRIGAN.
TELL BUS THIS PLACE THAT YOU'RE
VISITING TODAY?
>> Reporter: THEY BASICALLY
BUILT A MINIATURE WORLD OF
POTENTIAL TERROR ATTACKS.
THE REAL GOAL IN TRAINING IS TO
TRY TO MAKE THINGS AS REALISTIC
AS POSSIBLE.
>> LET'S GO.
[SOUND OF GUNFIRE.
>> Reporter: AT THE FEDERAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT TRAINING CENTER IN
BRUNSWICK, GEORGIA, THEY USE
BLANK AMMUNITION BUT REAL ACTO
ACTORS.
>> WE CAN'T SIMULATE BEHAVIOR,
HAVE YOU TO USE PEOPLE TO
SIMULATE BEHAVIOR.
>> Reporter: 60,000 FEDERAL
AGENTS A YEAR COME TO THE
1600-ACRE SITE COMPLETE WITH
MOCK AIRPLANES, BARS AND A TEST
TRACK.
THE IMPORTANT THING IF
PERFORMING A PIT MA FEW SRE A
PIT MANEUVER IS LOCATION.
TERROR EVENTS FROM THE PAST LIKE
A SARAN GAS SUBWAY ATTACK ARE
REHEARSAYED BESIDES POTENTIAL
FUTURE ATTACKS LIKE IMPROVISED
EXPLOSIVE DEVICES.
>> WE ARE PREPARED DOMESTICALLY
FOR ANY TYPE OF TREAT AND WE
WILL BE ABLE TOO DEFEAT THAT
THREAT SHOULD IT OCCUR HERE IN
THE UNITED STATES.
>> Reporter: RESPONSE TRAINING
TO ABDUCTIONS OR ACTIVE SHOOTERS
IS ONLY PART OF THE MISSION.
>> WE CAN'T AFFORD TO JUST
RESPOND TO INCIDENTS ANY MORE.
WE HAVE TO PREVENT THINGS FROM
HAPPENING.
>> Reporter: YOU GET A REAL
SENSE HERE FROM TALKING TO THE
INSTRUCTORS OF JUST HOW URGENT
THEY FEEL ABOUT TRYING NOT JUST
TO TRAIN RESPONDERS BUT TO TRY
TO PREVENT FUTURE ATTACKS.
MARTHA.
MARTHA: THAT IS FASCINATING.
LOOK OUT BEHIND YOU THERE IS A
LITTLE BIT OF SMOKE COMING OUT
OF THAT TRUCK BACK THERE,
STEVE.
VERY INTERESTING LOOK, THANK YOU
SO MUCH.
BRUNSWICK, GEORGIA THEY ARE
LEARNING ALL THAT.
BILL: LET'S PUT IT TO USE.
BREAKING NEWS IN THE FINANCIAL
CRISIS THAT IS FACING ANY
AMERICAN, WORD OF A BACK UP
PLAN, PLAN B, DETAILS OF WHAT
THE HOUSE SPEAKER JUST OUTLINED
AND WHAT IT COULD MEAN FOR EACH
AND EVERY ONE OF YOU.
MARTHA: WE LEAVE YOU WITH
THIS INTERESTING ROYAL
TIDBIT TODAY.
THE QUEEN OF ENGLAND RAISED
SOME EYEBROWS BECAUSE SHE
MADE A VISIT TO DOWNING
STREET.
USUALLY DOWNING STREET COMES
TO THE QUEEN BUT SAT IN ON A
CABINET MEETING.
THAT IS THE FIRST TIME A
SITTING MONARCH HAS DONE
THAT SINCE QUEEN VICTORIA
SAT IN ON CABINET MEETINGS.
WAS SET