HERE IS A SAMPLING.
OKAY WITH TAX RACE OR
1 MILLION PLUS EARNERS AS LONG
AS WE GET SIGNIFICANT SPENDING
CUTS NOW.
NOT JUST EMPTY PROMISES.
WE NEED LEADERSHIP IN
WASHINGTON.
BOTH SIDES HAVE NO IDEA WHAT
THEY ARE DOING.
ROB SAID IT DEPENDS ON THE
CUTS.
I LIKE THE FACT THAT
COMPROMISE IS IN THE WORKS
THOUGH, THAT IS HOW GOVERNMENT
IS SUPPOSED TO WORK.
THANKS FOR SHARING WITH US.
A LOT OF YOU HAD THINGS TO SAY
ABOUT WHETHER OR NOT SPEAKER
BOEHNER SHOULD REMAIN SPEAKER
BOEHNER.
THAT'S FOR ANOTHER DAY.
THAT'S FOR US HERE IN
WASHINGTON, "FOX NEWS SUNDAY"
IS UP NEXT.
I'M SHANNON BREAM.
THANKS FOR WATCHING AND BE
SURE TO REACH OUT TO THOSE
AROUND YOU WHO YOU KNOW ARE IN
NEED TODAY.
>> I'M CHRIS WALLACE.
A DEADLY GRADE SCHOOL SHOOTING
IN CONNECTICUT LEAVES
OFFICIALS, PARENTS, AND THE
NATION SEARCHING FOR ANSWERS.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS
OLD.
>> WE'LL HAVE LIVE REPORTS
FROM THE SCENE WITH THE LATEST
ON THE INVESTIGATION AND THE
VICTIMS.
WE'LL TALK WITH POLICE,
PARENTS OF SOME OF THE
CHILDREN WHO ATTEND THE
SCHOOL.
AND WITH THE STATE'S LONG-TIME
SENATOR JOE LIEBERMAN.
>> THEN WILL THERE BE A NEW
PUSH ON CAPITOL HILL FOR
CUFFER GUN CONTROL?
WE HEAR THE SAME CALLS AFTER
EVERY MASS SHOOTING.
BUT WILL THE HORRIFIC NATURE
OF THIS CRIME CHANGE THE
DEBATE?
WE'LL ASK DEMOCRATIC SENATOR
DICK DURBIN AND REPUBLICAN
CONGRESSMAN LIEU EGO MERIT.
WE'LL ALSO LOOK AT WHAT WE CAN
DO BETTER TO PROTECT OUR
CHILDREN WHEN WE TALK WITH
RONALD STEVENS, ONE OF THE
NATION'S TOP EXPERTS ON SCHOOL
SAFETY.
>> Chris: AND OUR SUNDAY PANEL
WEIGHS IN ON A CRIME OF MASS
VIOLENCE THAT IS BECOMING MUCH
TOO FAMILIAR.
>> OUR SPECIAL SCHOOL TRAGEDY
COVERAGE BEGINS RIGHT NOW ON
"FOX NEWS SUNDAY."
AND HELLO AGAIN FROM FOX NEWS
IN WASHINGTON.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN.
THAT'S HOW PRESIDENT OBAMA
RESPONDED FRIDAY TO THE
SLAUGHTER OF 27 PEOPLE.
20 OF THEM LITTLE CHILDREN AS
HE SPOKE TO AND FOR THE
NATION.
TODAY, WE'LL TRY TO MAKE SOME
SENSE OF THE SENSELESS ACT OF
VIOLENCE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE'LL TALK WITH OUR GUESTS IN
A MOMENT BUT FIRST HERE IS THE
LATEST FROM NEW TOWN
CONNECTICUT.
AUTHORITIES SAY ALL THE
CHILDREN FIRST GRADERS, SIX OR
SEVEN YEARS OLD WERE SHOT
MULTIPLE TIMES.
THE SIX ADULT VICTIMS WERE ALL
WOMEN.
POLICE SAY THEY HAVE GOOD
EVIDENCE ABOUT THE SUSPECT
ADAM LANZA BUT B. WHY HE
CARRIED OUT OTHE MASSACRE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL SPEAK AT
THE LOCAL HIGH SCHOOL AND MEET
WITH THE FAMILIES OF THE
VICTIMS.
FOR MORE ON THE INVESTIGATION
WE TURN TO FOX NEWS
CORRESPONDENT MIKE TOBIN IN
NEWTOWN.
MIKE?
>> GOOD MORNING, CHRIS.
PEOPLE HERE IN NEW TOWN ARE
FLOCKING TO THE CHURCHES ONCE
AGAIN TO MOURN AND TRY TO
COMPREHEND THE
INCOMPREHENSIBLE AS WE LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE HORRIBLE
DETAILS OF WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
DETAILS FROM THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER GRUESOME.
CLOSE RANGE.
THOSE LIVES JUST GETTING
STARTED 8 LITTLE BOYS AND 12
LITTLE GIRLS 6 AND 7 YEARS
OLD.
>> I HAVE BEEN AT THIS FOR A
THIRD OF A CENTURY.
MY SENSIBILITIES MAY NOT BE
THE AVERAGE MAN BUT THIS
PROBABLY IS THE WORST I HAVE
SEEN OR THE WORST THAT I KNOW
OF ANY OF MY COLLEAGUES HAVING
SEEN.
>> SIX OF THE VICTIMS AT THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
WERE STANDOFF.
THE PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG
SAID TO BE KILLED LUNGING AT
THE GUNMAN.
SUR LOCK ALSO KILLED.
THE MOTHER OF THE SHOOTER WAS
FOUND DEAD.
POLICE FOUND EVIDENCE THEY
HOPE WILL EXPLAIN THE
MOTIVATION OF THE GUNMAN.
>> THE SECONDARY CRIME SCENE
THAT WE DISCUSSED WHERE THE
FEMALE WAS LOCATED DECEASED
DID PRODUCE SOME VERY GOOD
EVIDENCE IN THIS
INVESTIGATION.
>> THAT GUNMAN, 20-YEAR-OLD
ADAM LANZA.
REPORTS SAY HE HAD THE
DISORDER AS BERGER'S SYNDROME.
HIS AUNT SAID HE WAS TROUBLED
AND NEEDED TO BE HOME
SCHOOLED.
>> HE WAS DIFFERENT.
HE WAS QUIET.
NICE KID.
GOOD KID.
I MEAN, HE WAS DEFINITELY A
CHALLENGE TO THE FAMILY IN
THAT HOUSE.
>> IN CONNECTICUT MAKESHIFT
MEMORIALS GROW WHERE HEARTS
ARE BROKEN.
PEOPLE DRAW ON THE BONDS SMALL
TOWN AMERICAN FOR STRENGTH TO
ENDURE THE SADNESS.
THEY HEAR THE STORIES TOLD BY
PARENTS LIKE PARKER ABOUT THE
LAST TIME HE SAW HIS
6-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER EMILY.
>> SHE TOLD ME GOOD MORNING.
AND ASKED HOW I WAS DOING.
I SAID I PASS WAS DOING WELL.
SHE SAID THAT SHE LOVED ME AND
I GAVE HER A KISS AND I WAS
OUT THE DOOR.
>> FEDERAL AGENTS ARE NOW
FANNING OUT TO GUN STORES AND
GUN RANGES ACROSS CONNECTICUT.
FOLLOWING LEADS AND TRYING TO
PIECE TOGETHER A TIME LINE OF
WHAT LED UP TO THIS TREMENDOUS
LOSS OF LIFE.
CHRIS?
>> MIKE TOBIN REPORTING FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
MIKE, THANKS FOR THAT.
NOW, LET'S BRING IN FOX NEWS
CORRESPONDENT MOLLY LINE.
WHO HAS BEEN FINDING OUT MORE
ABOUT THE VICTIMS OF THE
SHOOTING RAMPAGE.
MOLLY?
>> CHRIS, ALL ACROSS THIS
SMALL COMMUNITY, PEOPLE ARE
JUST BEGINNING TO COME TO
GRIPS WITH THEIR GRIEF AND
THEY ARE COMING TOGETHER.
JOINED THROUGH PRAYER AND
MOURNING.
>> THE SMALL MAKESHIFT
MEMORIALS ARE EVERYWHERE.
FLOWERS, BALLOONS AND
HANDWRITTEN SIGNS.
SOME TALKED WITH CHRISTMAS
DECORATIONS A REMINDER OF
CELEBRATIONS THAT FOR MANY
FAMILIES IN THIS TIGHTLY NIT
COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN WILL
NEVER BE.
>> ONE OF THE MOTHERS TOLD ME
ON THURSDAY HE ASKED HER WHAT
DYING WAS ABOUT.
AND, YOU KNOW, THEN THE NEXT
DAY HE DIED.
>> MONDAY SENIOR ROBERT WEISS
IS ACCUSTOMED TO COVER THE
GRIEVED.
I-PEOPLE MOVE HERE BECAUSE
THIS IS A SAFE PLACE, A SMALL
TOWN WHERE NEIGHBORS KNOW
NEIGHBORS.
DANA LIVES MERE THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
>> I'M NUMBED STILL.
YOU HEAR ABOUT THIS HAPPENING
BUT NEVER HERE IN YOUR
BACKYARD.
>> OVER THE NEXT SEVERAL DAYS
THERE WILL BE DOZENS OF
FUNERALS AND MEMORIAL SERVICES
HERE.
THEN THE DAUNTING TASK OF
TRYING TO RETURN TO SOME SENSE
OF NORMALCY.
>> WHAT'S NEXT WEEK GOING TO
BE LIKE FOR THE CHILDREN WHO
SURVIVE THIS?
HOW ARE THEY GOING TO WALK
INTO THAT SCHOOL?
HOW ARE THEY GOING TO KEEP
MOVING FORWARD?
HOW ARE THEY GOING TO FEEL
SAFE?
WHO ARE THEY GOING TO TRUST?
>> MANY HERE KNOW THIS IS AN
ENDURING LOSS AND PATH FORWARD
WILL BE A LONG ONE.
CHRIS?
>> MOLLY, THANK YOU.
IT IS A PARENT'S WORST
NIGHTMARE.
YOU GET A CALL YOUR CHILD'S
SCHOOL IS IN LOCKDOWN.
SOME FAMILIES IN NEWTOWN GOT
THAT CALL FRIDAY.
CALLS THAT LED TO RELIEF OR
DESPAIR.
JOINING US NOW IS ROBERT
LOCATA HIS SON ADEN IS A FIRST
GRADER SAVED BY HIS TEACHER
AND RAN TO SAFETY.
HIS DAUGHTER WAS ALSO
UNHARMED.
ALSO JOINING US JOE AND LYNN
WASSICK AS WELL AS THEIR
DAUGHTER ALEXIS WHO WAS IN THE
3RD GRADE AT SANDY HOOK.
TWO DAYS LATER, ROBERT, HOW IS
YOUR FAMILY DOING?
>> YOU KNOW, WE ARE TAKING IT
DAY BY DAY AND MINUTE BY
MINUTE.
IT'S WHAT BOTH OUR SON AND OUR
DAUGHTER SAW IS
INCOMPREHENSIBLE.
WE'RE TRYING TO MAKE SENSE OF
A SENSELESS ACT.
WE SPEAK TO HIM.
WE MAKE SURE WE UNDERSTAND
WHAT HE IS FEELING.
WE TRY TO EXPLAIN THINGS THAT
CAN'T BE EXPLAINED.
AND WE TAKE STOCK IN OUR FAITH
AND IN OUR COMMUNITY, OUR
NEIGHBORS AND OUR FRIENDS WHO
HAVE BEEN JUST TREMENDOUS.
>> LYNN AND JOE.
AND LITTLE ALEXIS, I SEE THERE
IN FRONT OF YOU.
DOES ALEXIS WANT TO TALK ABOUT
IT AND IF SO WHAT ARE YOU
TELLING HER?
>> AS FAR AS TALKING, WE
HAVEN'T -- WE'RE BREAKING IT
TO HER SLOWLY.
WE'RE NOT TRYING TO PRY TOO
MUCH IF SHE IS FORTH COMING IN
TELLING US STUFF, WE'RE
ALLOWING IT, YOU KNOW, WE'RE
LETTING HER COME OUT SLOWLY.
WE'RE NOT PRYING INTO HER, YOU
KNOW, WHAT HAPPENED.
WE DON'T WANT TO DO THAT.
>> ROBERT, YOUR SON, ADEN, IS
IN THE FIRST GRADE.
AND I UNDERSTAND THAT THE
GUNMAN BURST INTO HIS
CLASSROOM AND WAS CON FRONTED
AND SHOT HIS VERY BRAVE
TEACHER.
WE WILL TALK ABOUT HER IN A
MINUTE.
VICTORIA SOTO.
WHAT DID ADEN DO AFTER THAT.
>> WE'RE FINDING OUT MORE AND
MORE EVERY DAY.
BUT HE BASICALLY THE CHILDREN
WITNESSED THE SHOOTER COME
INTO THE ROOM.
SHOOT HIS TEACHER, CONTINUE
FIRING.
THE CHILDREN ACTED ON INSTINCT
AND WHAT THEY WERE TAUGHT,
WHICH WAS TO RUN.
AND THEY DID.
THEY JUST RAN UP TO THE MAIN
ROAD 100 YARDS AWAY.
MY SON AND SEVERAL OF HIS
OTHER STUDENTS WERE EXTREMELY
BRAVE IN WHAT THEY DID AND
ACTED WITH COURAGE THAT I
DON'T KNOW THAT I HAVE.
AND AGAIN, THEY JUST RAN AND
WERE FORTUNATE ENOUGH TO MEET
A WOMAN WHO WAS -- IS ANOTHER
HERO IN THE STORY AND TOOK
THEM TO THE POLICE STATION.
>> Chris: I UNDERSTAND.
>> THEY JUST JUST RAN.
>> I UNDERSTAND THAT ADEN NOT
ONLY WAITED FOR ADEN TO MAKE
SURE HE WAS SAFE.
TELL US ABOUT VICTORIA SOTO.
COMING OUT THIS 27-YEAR-OLD
FIRST GRADE TEACHER ACTUALLY
TRIED TO PERSUADE THE GUNMAN
NOT TO SHOOT AND PUT HERSELF
IN FRONT OF THE GUNMAN AND
LOST HER LIFE TRYING TO SAVE
HER CHILDREN.
TELL US ABOUT HER.
>> YOU KNOW, THE SCHOOL YEAR
WAS REGULARRIVELY KNEW.
MY WIFE KNEW HER A LITTLE BIT
BETTER THAN I DID.
I DID MEET HER ON ONE
OCCASION.
AND MY WIFE SPOKE VERY HIGHLY
OF HER.
SHY WAS VERY COMPASSION NOT
YOUNG WOMAN.
SHE LOVED THEM IN RETURN.
SHE WAS VERY SPECIAL AND WE'LL
ALWAYS REMEMBER HER.
>> AND LYNN AND JOE, THERE
WERE OTHER REMARKABLE ACTS OF
BRAVERY NONE GREATER THAN THE
PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG.
WE UNDERSTAND THAT WHEN SHE
HEARD THE GUNFIRE SHE RAN
TOWARDS IT NOT AWAY FROM IT OF
IT AND APPARENTLY LUNGED AT
THE SHOOTER TRYING TO SAVE THE
STUDENTS.
LENDED UP LOSING HER OWN LIFE.
TELL US ABOUT DAWN WAS
PHENOMENAL.
I HAD SEEN HER JUST ABOUT
EVERY MORNING.
ALEXUS IS PART OF THE BEFORE
AND AFTER SCHOOL PROGRAM AT
THE SCHOOL.
AND EVERY DAY THAT I WOULD SEE
DAWN, IT WAS ALWAYS DAWN HAS
AN INFECTIOUS SMILE.
SHE WAS SO CARING.
SHY GOT DOWN TO THE CHILDREN'S
LEVEL.
SHE PARTICIPATED WITH IN SO
MANY ACTIVITIES WITH THE
CHILDREN AND SHE DRESSED UP
WHEN THEY HAD A SOCK HOP LAST
YEAR AND SHE ACTUALLY WEPT IN
AND DANCED WITH THE CHILDREN
IF THEY SOLD 3,000 BOOKS SHE
DRESSED UP AS BOOK FAIRY.
SHE WAS A WONDERFUL WONDERFUL
PERSON.
THERE IS NO WORDS TO DESCRIBE
THE LOSS THAT WE ALL AS A
COMMUNITY HAVE FELT AND NOT
ONLY HER FAMILY.
>> ROBERT, YOU KNOW, ADEN
KNOWS SOME OF THE FAMILIES WHO
LOST CHILDREN IN THIS.
SOME OF THEM WERE HIS
CLASSMATES.
FIRST GRADE CLASS OF VICTORIA
SOCIETY TO.
IN THIS SENSE IS THAT BITTER
SWEET THAT YOU HAVE ADEB AND
OLDER DAUGHTER ALSO AT THE
SCHOOL KALINE AND SOME OF YOUR
NEIGHBORS DON'T?
>> YEAH.
IT'S A SMALL COMMUNITY.
RIGHT?
SO, ALL OF THE CHILDREN KNOW
EACH OTHER FROM PRESCHOOL.
THEY GO TO CHURCH TOGETHER.
THEY HAVE PLAY DATES TOGETHER.
WENER THOUGHT HE WAS GONE BUT
HE COULD HAVE VERY WELL BEEN
ONE OF THOSE THAT WERE
AFFECTED.
WE FEEL VERY BLESSED.
AND IT IS BITTERSWEET BECAUSE
WE DO, WHILE WE FEEL BLESSED
THAT WE STILL HAVE OUR SON AND
OUR DAUGHTER, WE MOURN FOR OUR
FRIENDS AND NEIGHBORS WHO
WEREN'T AS FORTUNATE AND LOST
THEIR CHILDREN.
>> Chris: LYNN, FINALLY I
GUESS THIS IS THE HARDEST
QUESTION, HOW DO YOU MAKE
SENSE OF THIS?
THERE IS NO SENSE.
THERE IS ABSOLUTELY NO SENSE
TO THIS I THINK I'M STILL VERY
NUMB.
LIKE ROBERT SAID WE ARE
BLESSED HAVING OUR DAUGHTER
WITH US US HERE TODAY.
HOW MANY FAMILIES AND FRIENDS
AND EVERYONE IN THE COMMUNITY
DIDN'T GO HOME WITH THEIR
CHILDREN FRIDAY NIGHT.
IT'S JUST VERY VERY HEART
WRENCHING AND THERE IS NO --
THERE IS NO WAY TO MAKE ANY
SENSE OF ANYTHING WHAT THIS
PERSON HAS DONE.
NOT ONLY TO FAMILIES BUT TO A
COMMUNITY, TO A NATION, AND
IT'S JUST UNFATHOMABLE.
YOU JUST DON'T.
WHO WOULD HAVE EVER THOUGHT
HERE IN THIS NEW TOWN OF 20
SOME ODD THOUSAND PEOPLE.
THAT'S WHY PEOPLE ARE HERE.
IT'S A SMALL, WONDERFUL
COMMUNITY WHERE PEOPLE ARE --
THEY JUST COME TOGETHER.
AS WE WERE COMING THROUGH TOWN
THERE IS A BANNER THAT SAYS WE
WILL BE STRONG AS A COMMUNITY
AND WE WILL REMAIN STRONG AND
WE'LL ALWAYS BE HERE FOR
ANYONE AND WITH EVERYONE IN
OUR COMMUNITY AND WITHIN OUR
SCHOOL.
>> LYNN AND JOE AND ALEXUS AND
ROBERT WE WANT TO THANK YOU
ALL SO MUCH FOR SHARING YOUR
STORIES AND JUST KNOW THAT OUR
PRAYERS AND THE PRAYERS OF THE
NATION ARE WITH YOU AND ALL
YOUR NEIGHBORS IN NEWTOWN.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Chris: FRIDAY'S MASS
SHOOTING IS THE WORST IN
CONNECTICUT HISTORY SECOND
WORST EVER IN THIS COUNTRY.
COLD NUMBERS ONLY MAGNIFY THE
FACT THAT THE SO MANY OF THE
VICTIMS WERE SMALL CHILDREN.
JOINING US NOW IS JOE
LIEBERMAN WHO HAS REPRESENTED
CONNECTICUT FOR 24 YEARS.
THANK YOU FOR COMING IN ON
THIS DIFFICULT WEEKEND.
>> THANK YOU, CHRIS.
>> Chris: WHAT DO WE DO?
>> YOU KNOW AS LYNN SAID,
THERE IS NO ANSWER, I MEAN,
THIS IS EVIL.
WE HAVE BEEN THROUGH THIS MANY
TIMES.
I THINK WE NEED A NATIONAL
COMMISSION ON MASS VIOLENCE.
NOT TO BE IN PLACE OF ANYTHING
ELSE THE PRESIDENT OR CONGRESS
OR STATE GOVERNMENTS MIGHT
WANT TO DO BUT TO MAKE SURE
THAT HEART BREAK AND THE ANGER
THAT WE FEEL NOW IS NOT
DISSIPATED OVER TIME OR LOST
IN LEGISLATIVE GRIDLOCK.
I HAVE GOT TO TELL YOU, THIS
REMINDS ME OF THE DAYS AND
WEEKS AFTER THE TERRORIST
ATTACKS AGAINST US OF 9/11.
AND AT ONE POINT, JOHN MCCAIN
AND I TURNED TO EACH OTHER AND
SAID WE CAN'T LET THIS JUST
GO.
WE HAVE GOT TO CREATE A
NATIONAL COMMISSION TO
INVESTIGATE EXACTLY THE
QUESTIONS WE ARE ASKING ABOUT
NEW TOWN.
HOW COULD THIS HAVE HAPPENED
AND IS THERE ANYTHING WE CAN
DO TO TRY TO PREVENT IT FROM
HAPPENING AGAIN.
>> THERE WERE FORUMS AFTER
9/11 AND AFTER THE COMMISSION
AND THE WAY THAT THE
INTELLIGENCE COMMUNITY AND THE
FBI SHARED INFORMATION.
IT WASN'T JUST LET'S WALLOW IN
OUR GRIEF.
>> NO.
>> Chris: LET ME ASK YOU A
SPECIFIC QUESTION.
>> I WANT TO SAY VERY QUICKLY
THAT'S THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT I
DON'T WANT TO HAPPEN.
I DON'T WANT US TO WALLOW IN
OUR GRIEF.
I WANT US TO ASK WHAT CAN WE
DO AS A SOCIETY TO MAKE SURE
YOUNG MEMBER LIKE ADAM LANZA
GET HELP BEFORE THEY BECOME
SHOOTERS AND KILLERS.
WHAT'S THE ROLE OF VIOLENCE IN
OUR ENTERTAINMENT CULTURE
TODAY IT IN STIMULATING A
VULNERABLE KID LIKE THIS?
AND WHAT MORE CAN WE DO TO
KEEP DANGEROUS WEAPONS OUT OF
THE HANDS OF PEOPLE LIKE THIS?
>> Chris: LET ME ASK YOU ABOUT
SOME OF THOSE SPECIFIC
QUESTIONS.
BACK IN THE 90'S YOU SUPPORTED
THE BREATED LAW WHICH CALLED
FOR A FIVE DAY WAITING PERIOD.
>> RIGHT.
>> Chris: YOU AASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN.
YOU AND AL GORE CAMPAIGNED
AROUND THE COUNTRY AND YOU
LOST AND A LOT OF PEOPLE TOOK
AS A LESSEN PART OF IT WAS IN
STATES LIKE TENNESSEE AND WEST
VIRGINIA THE FACT THAT YOU
WERE PROGUN CONTROL AND QUITE
FRANKLY EVER SINCE DEMOCRATS
HAVE BEEN SCARED OF TOUCHING
THAT ISSUE.
IS IT FULL-TIME FOR DEMOCRATS
TO PUSH FOR STRICTER GUN
CONTROL?
>> IT'S TIME FOR DEMOCRATS,
REPUBLICANS AND INDEPENDENTS
TO SAY -- ACKNOWLEDGE TWO
THINGS.
ONE IS THE STRONGEST
CONCEIVABLE GUN CONTROL LAWS
WON'T STOP ALL ACTS OF
VIOLENCE.
BUT ALSO, TO ACKNOWLEDGE THAT
THE STRONGER OUR GUN CONTROL
LAWS ARE, THE FEWER ACTS OF
VIOLENCE, INCLUDING MASS
VIOLENCE THAT WILL HAPPEN ON
OUR SOCIETY.
SO, AS A RESULT OF THE BRADY
LAW, AND IT STILL EXISTS.
IF YOU GO IT NOAH A LICENSED
FIREARM DEALER YOU HAVE A
BACKGROUND CHECK AND IT'S A
THOROUGH ONE.
IF YOU BUY A GUN FROM SOMEBODY
WHO IS NOT LICENSED OR AT A
GUN SHOW, YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE
CHECKED AT ALL.
THAT'S A LOOPHOLE THAT WE
OUGHT TO CLOSE.
ASSAULT WEAPONS, THESE WERE
DEVELOPED BY THE U.S. MILITARY
ORIGINALLY AS WEAPONS OF WAR.
AND I THINK WE OUGHT TO
RESTORE THAT ASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN BECAUSE NOT TO TAKE
ANYBODY'S GUNS AWAY FROM THEM
THAT THEY HAVE NOW.
BUT IT TO STOP THE MANUFACTURE
AND SALE OF THOSE WEAPONS NOW
BECAUSE LOOK WHAT LANZA DID TO
THESE POOR KIDS.
>> LET'S TALK ABOUT A COUPLE
OF OTHER THINGS.
MENTAL ILLNESS.
>> YEAH.
>> THIS IS OBVIOUSLY A
DISTURBED BOY.
>> CORRECT.
>> SOME OTHER CASES HOLMES IN
AURORA DISTURBED.
THE ENTERTAINMENT INDUSTRY
THERE IS SOME STATISTICS ABOUT
KIDS WILL HAVE WATCHED
THOUSANDS OF ACTS OF VIOLENCE
ON VIDEOS, ON GAMES AND MOVIES
AND TV BY THE TIME, YOU KNOW,
THEY ARE 10.
SPECIFICALLY, WHAT KIND OF
THING CAN WE DO ABOUT THAT?
>> THAT'S WHY I THINK WE NEED
A NATIONAL COMMISSION.
I WILL TELL YOU I SPENT ENOUGH
TIME ON THIS QUESTION OF
VIOLENCE IN THE ENTERTAINMENT
CULTURE TO REACH THIS
CONCLUSION.
THAT THE VIOLENCE IN THE
ENTERTAINMENT CULTURE
PARTICULARLY WITH THE
EXTRAORDINARY REALISM TO VIDEO
GAME MOVIES ET CETERA DOES
CAUSE VULNERABLE YOUNG MEN,
PARTICULARLY TO BEING MORE
VIOLENT IT.
DOESN'T MAKE EVERYBODY MORE
VIOLENT BUT IT'S A CAUSATIVE
FACTOR IN SOME CASES.
WE HAVE GOT TO ASK THE
ENTERTAINMENT INDUSTRY WHAT
ARE TONE IT DOWN.
>> Chris: PASS A LAW.
>> IN OUR SOCIETY YOU TRY TO
DO IT VOLUNTARILY, YOU HAVE
COME TO A POINT TO SAY IF NOT
MAYBE THERE IS SOME THINGS WE
CAN DO TO TONE IT DOWN.
THERE IS A BETTER RATING
SYSTEM NOW THAN THERE USED TO
BE ON VIDEO GAMES AND VIOLENT
MOVIES.
THEY ARE STILL OUT THERE.
WHEN IT COMES TO THE MENTAL
HEALTH SYSTEM.
I THINK WE HAVE REALLY GOT TO
ASK OURSELVES FIRST OFF THIS
IS LIKE THE SLOGAN THAT WE USE
IN HOMELAND SECURITY.
SEE SOMETHING, SAY SOMETHING.
WE HAVE GOT TO ASK PARENTS,
FRIENDS, SCHOOL OFFICIALS IF
YOU SEE A CHILD, A YOUNG
PERSON THAT REALLY LOOKS LIKE
THEY ARE POTENTIALLY REALLY
TROUBLESOME, GET THEM MENTAL
HELP.
AND THEN WE HAVE GOT TO ASK
OURSELVES AS A SOCIETY, IS
THERE ENOUGH MENTAL HEALTH
HELP AVAILABLE FOR THESE KIDS?
THERE IS IS NO CURE.
VIOLENCE IS AS OLD AS CAIN
KILLING HIS BROTHER ABLE.
BUT GOD DIDN'T ACCEPT THAT AS
A GIVEN AND SAID IF I MAY TO
CAIN, WHERE IS YOUR BROTHER?
AND ABLE, CAIN SAYS AM I MY
BROTHER'S KEEPER?
AND GOD SAYS ESSENTIALLY YES.
I HEAR YOUR BROTHER'S BLOOD
CRYING OUT TO ME FROM THE
GROUND.
AND I THINK WE HAVE GOT TO
CONTINUE TO HEAR THE SCREAMS
OF THESE CHILDREN AND SEE
THEIR BLOOD UNTIL WE DO
SOMETHING TO TRY TO PREVENT
THIS FROM HAPPENING AGAIN.
VIGIL TONIGHT.
THANK YOU, SIR EVERYWHERE.
>> Chris: UP NEXT, WITH
ANOTHER MASS MURDER, NEW CALLS
FOR GUN CONTROL IS NOW THE
RIGHT TIME?
AS OUR COVERAGE OF THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT
CONTINUES.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S SIMPLE PHYSICS...
A BODY AT REST
TENDS TO STAY AT REST...
WHILE A BODY IN MOTION
TENDS TO STAY IN MOTION.
STAYING ACTIVE CAN ACTUALLY
EASE ARTHRITIS SYMPTO.
BUT IF YOU HAVE ARTHRITIS,
STAYING ACTIVE
CAN BE DIFFICULT.
PRESCRIPTION CELEBREX
CAN HELP RELIEVE ARTHRITIS PAIN
SO YOUR BODY
CAN STAY IN MOTION.
BECAUSE JUST ONE
200MG CELEBREX A DAY
CAN PROVIDE 24 HOUR RELIEF
FOR MANY WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND INFLAMMATION.
PLUS, IN CLINICAL STUDIES,
CELEBREX IS PROVEN TO IMPROVE
DAILY PHYSICAL FUNCTION
SO MOVING IS EASIER.
CELEBREX CAN BE TAKEN WITH
OR WITHOUT FOOD.
AND IT'S NOT A NARCOTIC.
WITH
NAPROXEN, AND MELOXICAM
HAVE THE SAME
CARDIOVASCULAR WARNING.
THEY ALL MAY INCREASE
THE CHANCE
OF HEART ATTACK OR STROKE,
WHICH CAN LEAD TO DEATH.
THIS CHANCE INCREASES
IF YOU HAVE HEART DISEASE
RISK FACTORS
SUH AS HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE
OR WHEN NSAIDS ARE TAKEN
FOR LONG PERIODS.
NSAIDS, INCLUDING CELEBREX,
INCREASE THE CHANCE OF SERIOUS
SKIN OR ALLERGIC REACTIONS
OR STOMACH A INTESTINE
PROBLEMS,
SUCH AS BLEEDING AND CERS,
WHICH CAN OCCUR WITHOUT WARNING
AND MAY CAUSE DEATH.
PATIENTS ALSO TAKING ASPIRIN
AND THE ELDEY
ARE AT INCRSED RISK FOR
STOCH BLEEDING AND ULCERS.
DO NOT TAKE CELEBREX IF YOU'VE
HAD AN ASTHMA ATTACK, HIVES,
OR OTHER ALLERGIES TO ASPIRIN,
NSAIDS OR SULFONAMIDES.
GET HELP RIGHTWAY IF YOU HAVE
SWELNG OF THE FACE OR THROAT,
OR TROUBLE BREATHING.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
YOUR MEDICAL HISTORY
AND FIND AN ARTHRITIS TREATMENT
FOR YOU.
VISIT CELEBREX.COM AND ASK
YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT CELEBREX.
FOR A BODY IN MOTION.
SUGGESTING IS NOW TIME TO
REOPEN THE NATIONAL DEBATE ON
GUN CONTROL.
AS HORRIFIC AS THIS SHOOTING
HAS BEEN WE HAVE WITHIN HERE
BEFORE AS A NATION.
THERE HAS BEEN LITTLE INTEREST
IN THE LAST DECADE IN
TIGHTENING GUN LAWS.
JOINING ME NOW IS DICK DURBIN
IN HIS HOME STATE OF ILLINOIS.
SENATOR, HOW DO YOU READ THE
PRESIDENT'S COMMENTS THAT WE
JUST PLAYED?
IS IT TIME FOR A NEW PUSH,
TIGHTER GUN CONTROL?
>> WELL, FIRST, LET ME SAY THE
NATION IS IN MOURNING AND
REFLECTION AND PRAYER OVER
WHAT HAPPENED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT THERE ISN'T A
PARENT OR GRANDPARENT THAT
DIDN'T VISUALIZE SOME SOMEONE
THEY LOVE SUBJECTED TO THIS
KIND OF VIOLENCE WHY NEED A
NATIONAL CONVERSATION OF THE
JOE LIEBERMAN CALLED.
WE NEED A NATIONAL
CONVERSATION ABOUT SAFETY.
I WOULD GO BEYOND JOE AND SAY
LET'S ADD THAT ISSUE OF SCHOOL
SAFETY INTO THIS CONVERSATION
AS WELL.
GUN CONTROL IS PART OF IT WE
NEED TO SIT DOWN AND HAVE A
QUIET CALM REFLECTION ON THE
SECOND AMENDMENT?
ARE THERE GUNS THAT SHOULDN'T
BE SOLD ACROSS AMERICA.
MILITARY ASSAULT WEAPONS SUCH
AS THE ONE INVOLVED IN THIS
HORRIFIC INCIDENT N
CONNECTICUT?
ARE THERE HIGH AM MISSION
CLIPS?
HIGH CLIPS THAT HAVE NO VALUE
WHATSOEVER WHEN IT COMES TO
SPORTING AND HUNTING AND EVEN
SELF-DEFENSE.
THAT A PERSON COULD BUY BODY
ARMOR, TAKE THAT BODY ARMOR
AND USE IT TO PROTECT
THEMSELVES AS THEY KILL
INNOCENT PEOPLE?
CAN WE HAVE A THOUGHTFUL, CALM
REFLECTION ON THESE THINGS DO
IT IN THE CONTEXT OF OUR
SECOND AMENDMENT?
I THINK WE NEED TO.
>> Chris: THE PRESIDENT AS WE
HAD IN THAT CLIP MENTIONED
REGARDLESS OF POLITICS AND THE
FACT IS THAT WE HAD THAT
SLAUGHTER OF PEOPLE AT THE
MOVIE THEATER IN AURORA,
COLORADO JUST IN JULY AT THAT
TIME YOU SAID YOU SUPPORTED A
BAN ON ASSAULT WEAPONS.
YOU ALSO SAID.
>> I DO.
>> Chris: BACK AT THAT TIME
THERE IS ZERO CHANCE THAT
CONGRESS WILL PASS THAT.
IT'S NOT JUST REPUBLICANS,
QUITE FRANKLY AS I POINTED OUT
TO JOE LIEBERMAN YOUR PARTY
HAS BEEN AFRAID BECAUSE OF
POLITICS TO PUSH THIS FOR THE
LAST DECADE.
CHRIS, THERE IS PLENTY OF
BLAME ON BOTH SIDES
POLITICALLY.
THERE IS ALSO A RESPONSIBILITY
OF THE PEOPLE ACROSS THIS
NATION I WOULD APPEAL TO THE
HUNTERS AND SPORTSMEN I KNOW
THEM.
THEY ARE GOOD PEOPLE.
THEY LOVE THEIR FAMILIES.
THEY HEAR WHAT THEY ARE
HEARING ABOUT NEW TOWN,
CONNECTICUT BUT THEY HAVE BEEN
LARGELY QUIET.
THIS CONVERSATION HAS BEEN
DOMINATED IN WASHINGTON BY,
YOU KNOW AND I KNOW, GUN
LOBBIES THAT HAVE AN AGENDA.
WE NEED FOR HERMINE, JUST
ORDINARY AMERICANS TO COME
TOGETHER AND SPEAK OUT AND TO
SIT DOWN AND CALMLY REFLECT ON
HOW FAR WE GO.
I'M GOING TO BE HOLDING A
HEARING AFTER THE THE
YEAR IN ABOUT TWO WEEKS OR SO
ON THIS CONSTITUTIONAL
QUESTION.
THAT'S THE STARTING POINT.
THE SUPREME COURT RAISED
QUESTIONS ABOUT THE SECOND
AMENDMENT, WHAT ARE THE
PROTECTIONS?
WHAT ARE THE RESPONSIBILITIES?
LET'S SPELL THIS OUT?
AND LET'S TRY TO DO IT IN A
THOUGHTFUL WAY AND MOVE
FORWARD TOGETHER.
THAT'S WHAT WE NEED.
>> Chris: LET'S DEAL WITH SOME
THE ARGUMENTS AGAINST NEW GUN
LAWS.
THE FACT IS THAT CONNECTICUT
SENATOR AS YOU PELL KNOW HAS
SOME OF THE TOUGHEST GUN LAWS
IN THE COUNTRY.
NANCY LANZA, THE MOTHER OF THE
SHOOTER HAD BOUGHT AND
REGISTERED THESE GUNS LEGALLY.
WHAT MORE CAN WE DO?
>> WELL, LISTEN, WHY IN THE
WORLD WOULD ANYONE, EVEN NANCY
LANZA NEED A MILITARY ASSAULT
WEAPON DESIGNED FOR THE
MILITARY THAT HAS THE CAPACITY
TO FIRE OFF HUNDREDS OF
ROUNDS?
HEART BREAKING TO HEAR THIS
CORONER SPEAK ABOUT THESE POOR
LITTLE KIDS WHOSE BODIES WERE
RIDDLED WITH BULLETS FOR
GOODNESS SAKES.
CAN WE STOP FOR A MOMENT AND
REFLECT ON THIS?
I'M ALL FOR SPORT AND HUNTING
AND SELF-DEFENSE.
THIS GOES WAY BEYOND THAT.
>> Chris: FINALLY, SENATOR,
BLAB THOSE PEOPLE WHO SAY AND
OUR NEXT GUEST CONGRESSMAN
GOHMERT IS ONE OF THEM THAT
THE REAL ANSWER IS NOT FEWER
GUNS BUT MORE GUNS SO THAT IF
A PERSON LIKE THIS COMES TO A
MOVIE THEATER OR A MALL OR A
SCHOOL, SOMEBODY IS THERE WHO
CAN TAKE THEM DOWN.
>> I JUST -- I HONESTLY THINK
THAT THAT ARGUMENT U.S. IS --
ARGUMENT JUST DOESN'T HOLD
WATER.
TALKING ABOUT ARMING TEACHERS
AND PRINCIPALS?
IS THAT GOING TO MAKE US A
SAFER AMERICA?
I DON'T THINK SO.
TOO MANY PEOPLE ARE HARMED BY
FIREARMS, THEIR OWN FIREARMS
THAT ARE ACCIDENTLY MISUSED OR
TURN ON THEM.
I DON'T HAPPEN TO BUY THAT
APPROACH AT ALL.
I WANT TO SIT DOWN AND CALMLY
DISCUSS ALL THE OPTIONS.
I THINK WE NEED TO DO THAT AS
A NATION.
THAT'S THE ONLY WAY WE CAN
MOVE FORWARD AND MAKE SURE
THAT THERE IS A LESSON TO BE
LEARNED IN NEW TOWN
CONNECTICUT.
>> LET ME JUST ASK YOU AFTER
AURORA YOU SAID THERE WAS ZERO
CHANCE CONGRESS WOULD PASS A
NEW LAW.
DO YOU STILL SAY ZERO CHANCE?
>> NO.
I THINK THAT WHAT HAPPENED IN
NEW TOWN, CONNECTICUT, MAY AT
LEAST LEAD SOME TO FINALLY
DECIDE TO SIT DOWN AND TO HAVE
THIS CONVERSATION.
I REALLY THINK WE MAY HAVE A
CHANCE BECAUSE OF THIS
TERRIBLE TRAGEDY.
THAT'S WHAT HAPPENED AFTER
9/11.
IT CAN HAPPEN AFTER NEW TOWN
CONNECTICUT AS WELL.
>> Chris: SENATOR DURBIN,
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US
TODAY, SIR.
>> THANK YOU.
>> THE CORE OF THE DEBATE GOES
TO A BASIC CONSTITUTIONAL
PROVISION THE RIGHT TO BEAR
ARMS.
DOES THIS TRAGEDY CHANGE OR
LIMIT THAT?
JOINING ME NOW REPUBLICAN
CONGRESSMAN LOUIE GOHMERT OF
TEXAS.
CONGRESSMAN, WELCOME.
>> GREAT TO BE WITH YOU,
CHRIS.
>> Chris: ATTORNEY GENERAL
HOLDER SPOKE OUT ABOUT THE
SHOOTING ON FRIDAY.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT WHAT HE
SAID.
>> WE NEED TO DISCUSS WHO WE
ARE AS A NATION.
TALK ABOUT THE FREEDOMS THAT
WE HAVE.
THE RIGHTS THAT WE HAVE, AND
HOW THOSE MIGHT BE USED IN A
RESPONSIBLE WAY.
>> Chris: WHAT DO YOU THINK
ABOUT HIS COMMENTS ABOUT OUR
RIGHTS AND OUR FREEDOMS BEING
USED IN A RESPONSIBLE WAY?
>> WELL, I THINK COMING FROM
HIM, THAT'S REALLY IMPORTANT
TO NOTE.
COMING FROM A MAN WHO IS OVER
A DEPARTMENT THAT FORCED THE
SALE OF GUNS TO PEOPLE THAT
WOULD BRING ABOUT THE DEATH OF
PEOPLE LIKE BRIAN TERRY AND
THERE SHOULD BE NATIONAL
OUTRAGE ABOUT MEXICANS, OUR
NEIGHBORS, 200 OR MORE THAT
HAVE BEEN KILLED BY THE GUNS
THAT HIS DEPARTMENT HAVE
FORCIBLY OR FORCED TO BE SOLD.
SO, HE IS RIGHT.
AND REALLY, SENATOR DURBIN IS
RIGHT.
BUT THE CONVERSATION WE HAVE
GOT TO HAVE HAS GOT TO HAVE
EVERYBODY OPEN-MINDED.
I MEAN, WE ALL REACT
EMOTIONALLY, THAT'S WHY WE
HAVE ALL SHED TEARS AND OUR
PRAYERS WILL CONTINUE TO GO
FOR THE PEOPLE IN CONNECTICUT
WHO HAVE LOST LOVED ONES.
>> Chris: AFTER THE MOVIE HERE
IS THE SHOOTING IN JULY IN
AURORA, COLORADO, YOU SAID
WHAT WE NEED IS MORE PEOPLE
CARRYING WEAPONS SO THAT IF A
SHOOTER COMES INTO A MOVIE
THEATER WITH A GUN, SOMEBODY
CAN STAND UP AND DEFEND HIM
AND DEFEND OTHER PEOPLE.
QUESTION:  AND THIS IS THE
QUESTION DICK DURBIN HAD.
DO WE REALLY WANT FOLKS IN
MOVIE THEATERS, AND MALLS AND
SCHOOLS ARMED?
>> ONCE WE HAVE THIS ACTUALLY
OPEN DIALOGUE ABOUT EVER EVERY
MASS KILLING OF PEOPLE IN
RECENT HISTORY HAS BEEN IN A
PLACE WHERE GUNS WERE
PROHIBITED.
THESE GUN -- EXCEPT FOR ONE.
THEY CHOOSE THIS PLACE, THEY
KNOW NO ONE WILL BE ARMED.
YOU KNOW, HAVING BEEN A JUDGE
AND HAVING REVIEWED
PHOTOGRAPHS OF THESE HORRIFIC
SCENES AND KNOWING THAT
CHILDREN HAVE THESE DEFENSIVE
WOUNDS, GUNSHOTS THROUGH THEIR
ARMS AND HANDS AS THEY TRY TO
PROTECT THEMSELVES, AND
HEARING THE HEROIC STORIES OF
THE PRINCIPAL LUNGING TRYING
TO PROTECT, CHRIS, I WISH TO
GOD SHE HAD HAD AN M 4 IN HER
OFFICE LOCKED UP SO THAT WHEN
SHE HEARD GUNFIRE SHE PULLS IT
OUT AND SHE DIDN'T HAVE TO
LUNGE HEROICALLY WITH NOTHING
IN HIS HANDS TAKES HIM OUT AND
TAKES HIS HEAD OFF BEFORE HE
COULD KILL THOSE PRECIOUS
KIDS.
>> Chris: I UNDERSTAND THE
RIGHT TO BEAR ARMS AND THE
SUPREME COURT MEANT SUPREME
COURT WAS CLEAR WHEN THEY PUT
THE RIGHT TO BEAR ARMS IN THE
CONSTITUTION.
LET ME ASK YOU THE QUESTION
DICK DURBIN ASKED.
WHY DO PEOPLE NEED THESE
SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPONS?
I WAS READING ABOUT THE GLOCK
HE HAD AND THE SIGSOWER HE
HAD.
FIVE BULLETS A SECOND BUSH
MASTER.
THESE WERE CREATED FOR LAW
ENFORCEMENT.
THESE WERE CREATED FOR THE
MILITARY.
WHY DOES THE AVERAGE PERSON.
I CAN UNDERSTAND HUNTING RIFLE
AND HUNTING GUN.
WHY DO THESE WEAPONS OF MASS
DESTRUCTION.
>> FOR THE REASON THAT GEORGE
WASHINGTON SAID.
A FREE PEOPLE SHOULD BE AN
ARMED PEOPLE.
IT ENSURES AGAINST THE TYRANNY
OF THE GOVERNMENT.
IF THEY KNOW THAT THE BIGGEST
ARMY IS THE AMERICAN PEOPLE,
THEN YOU DON'T HAVE THE
TYRANNY THAT CAME FROM KING
GEORGE.
THAT'S WHY IT WAS PUT IN
THERE.
THAT'S WHY ONCE YOU START
DRAWING THE LINE WHERE DO YOU
STOP?
AND THAT'S WHY IT IS IMPORTANT
TO NOT JUST LOOK EMOTIONALLY.
OUR REACTION IS TO IMMEDIATELY
SAY LET'S GET RID OF ALL GUNS.
YOU DO AS IT A JUDGE.
YOU REACT EMOTIONALLY BUT YOU
USE YOUR HEAD AND YOU LOOK AT
THE FACTS.
AND THE FACTS ARE THAT EVERY
TIME GUNS HAVE BEEN ALLOWED,
CONCEAL CARRIES HAVE BEEN
ALLOWED.
THE CRIME RATE HAS GONE DOWN.
WASHINGTON, D.C. AROUND US
OUGHT TO BE THE SAFEST PLACE
IN AMERICA.
AND IT'S NOT.
CHICAGO OUGHT TO BE SAFE.
IT'S NOT.
BECAUSE THEIR GUN LAWS DON'T
WORK.
>> Chris: CONGRESSMAN, THANK
YOU.
THANKS FOR COMING IN TODAY.
WE WILL SEE WHERE THIS DEBATE
COMES FROM HERE.
>> THANKS SO MUCH.
>> Chris: UP NEXT, WE WILL
TALK WITH AN EXPERT ABOUT WHAT
CAN BE DONE TO MAKE OUR
SCHOOLS SAFER.
THEN OUR SUNDAY PANEL AS WE
CONTINUE OUR SPECIAL COVERAGE
OF THE TRAGEDY IN THE
CLASSROOM.
ABOUT TAKING ASPIRIN.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
>> Chris: THE SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL SHOOTING CONFRONT SOME
QUESTIONS IS MY CHILD'S SCHOOL
AS SAFE AS IT SHOULD BE.
WHAT MORE CAN BE DONE?
JOINING ME NOW FROM CALABASAS,
CALIFORNIA, IS RONALD STEVENS,
DIRECTOR OF THE NATIONAL
SCHOOL SAFETY CENTER.
SHEAND HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
HAD RECENTLY INSTALLED A NEW
SECURITY SYSTEM.
THE DOORS WERE LOCKED AT 9:30.
YOU HAD TO BE BUZZED IN.
TO GET INTO THE SCHOOL.
BUT POLICE SAY THE SHOOTER
FORCED HIS WAY IN SO I GUESS
THE QUESTION IS, WHAT MORE CAN
A SCHOOL DO?
>> IT'S A TREMENDOUS CHALLENGE
FOR SCHOOL OFFICIALS BECAUSE
SCHOOL CAMPUSES ARE NOT
DESIGNED TO BE FORTRESSES TO
BE DEFENDED.
THEY ARE PLACES OF LEARNING.
SO, THE EXPECTATION FOR
SCHOOLS IS THAT THEY WOULD
TAKE REASONABLE STEPS AND WHEN
WE LOOK AT THE COMPASSION AND
CARE AND SACRIFICE OF THE
ADMINISTRATORS AND TEACHERS,
THAT'S PROBABLY ONE OF THE
MOST SIGNIFICANT FACTORS BUT
BUNS AGAIN IF YOU HAVE AN
ARMED GETTING ON TO THE CAMPUS
THEY WILL USE USE WHATEVER
MEANS NECESSARY.
NOT UNCOMMON SITUATION WHERE
THEY DEFEAT SOME THE BEST
SYSTEMS THAT ARE IN PLACE.
>> Chris: I WAS FASCINATED,
MR. STEVENS, BY HOW MUCH
SECURITY AND I DIDN'T REALIZE
THIS A LOT OF OUR PUBLIC
SCHOOLS ALREADY HAVE, LET'S
TAKE A LOOK AT SOME OF THE
SECURITY MEASURES THAT ARE
ALREADY THERE.
92% OF PUBLIC SCHOOLS LOCK OR
MONITOR THEIR DOORS.
61% USE SECURITY CAMERAS.
63% USE ELECTRONIC
NOTIFICATION FOR A SCHOOL
EMERGENCY.
WHAT ARE THE BIG GAPS YOU
STILL SEE OUT THERE, SIR?
>> ONE OF THE BIGGEST GAPS
THAT I SEE IS THAT SCHOOLS SO
OFTEN ARE HELD TO ACCOUNT FOR
NOT SUPPOSED TO EVER BE
LETTING THESE KINDS OF
INCIDENTS OCCUR.
AND, YET, THE SCHOOLS REFLECT
SO MUCH WHAT'S GOING ON IN
SOCIETY.
WE WANT SCHOOLS TO TAKE STEPS
THAT ARE APPROPRIATE BUT THERE
ARE LIMITATIONS AND UNTIL
SOMEONE IS ABLE TO CONTROL THE
HUMAN MIND IN THESE CHOICES
THAT ARE MADE BY DERANGED
INDIVIDUALS, IT'S GOING TO BE
VERY DIFFICULT.
I THINK THIS NATIONAL
CONVERSATION THAT WE ARE
TALKING ABOUT HAS TO GO BEYOND
SCHOOLS IN THE COMMUNITIES AND
TO HOMES INTO.
GATHER.
KEEP OUR SAFER.
>> Chris: YOU HEARD WHAT
CONGRESSMAN GOHMERT JUST SAID,
DO WE NEED ARMED GUARDS INSIDE
SCHOOLS?
DO WE NEED A TEACHER OR SOME
KIND OF PERSONNEL, THE
PRINCIPAL WHO KNOWS AND HAS
HOW TO FIRE AND HAS A WEAPON
WITH HIM?
>> I WISH WE DIDN'T HAVE TO
HAVE ARMED GUARDS IN THE
SCHOOLS.
AND, YET, THE KINDS OF THINGS
THAT ARE HAPPENING NOW HAS
BEEN ONE OF THE CHIEF ITEMS
THAT HAS ENCOURAGED THE
PRESENCE OF SCHOOL RESOURCE
OFFICERS ALL ACROSS THE
COUNTRY.
BUT, EVEN ON THE BEST OF DAYS,
TO ASSUME THAT THE OFFICER
WILL ALWAYS BE IN THE RIGHT
PLACE AT THE RIGHT TIME AT THE
RIGHT MOMENT IS DIFFICULT.
YOU LOOK AT RED LAKE, MINUTE
SOCIETY THAT HAD OFFICERS AT
THE SCHOOLHOUSE GATE AS WELL
AS METAL DETECTORS AND YET THE
ASSAILANT COMES, IN TAKES OUT
THE OFFICER, WALKS RIGHT
THROUGH THE METAL DETECTORS.
THERE ARE THINGS THAT
OFTENTIMES SIMPLY CAN'T.
SCOPE AND CONTROL OF SCHOOL
OFFICIALS THAT THESE ARE ARE
SOME OF THE CHALLENGES THAT WE
FACE.
>> ONE THING THAT SEEMED
ABSOLUTELY CLEAR FROM WHAT
HAPPENED AT SANDY HOOK IS THEY
HAVE DONE A LOT OF TRAINING
THERE HAD BEEN A LOT OF SAFETY
DRILLS AND IT SURE SEEMED, IN
TERMS OF THE RESPONSE IN THE
CLASSROOMS AND EVACUATING THE
KIDS FROM THE SCHOOL THAT SURE
SEEMED TO MAKE A BIG
DIFFERENCE IN SAVING LIVES.
>> WELL, IT ABSOLUTELY DID.
AND WE'RE PROBABLY A LOT
BETTER AT CRISIS RESPONSE THAN
WE ARE AT CRISIS PREVENTION.
BUT HAVE THOSE DRILLS IN PLACE
TO HAVE WORKED WITH
ADMINISTRATOR STAFF, THE FIRST
RESPONDERS AND THE STUDENTS.
I THINK IS A REMARKABLE
TRIBUTE TO WHAT SCHOOL
OFFICIALS HAD DONE THERE.
BUT MY TAKE IS WE HAVE GOT TO
CONTINUE TO FOCUS MORE ON HOW
WE ADDRESS THIS WHOLE DEAL OF
THE CRISIS PREVENTION AT THE
OUTSET IN ADDITION TO SIMPLY
GOOD CRISIS RESPONSE.
>> MR. STEVENS, WE HAVE TO
LEAF IT THERE THANK YOU SO
MUCH FOR TALKING WITH US
THERE.
>> MY PLEASURE.
>> IN A HOLIDAY SEASON SHATTER
ITED BY GUNFIRE A GRIEVING
NATION ASKED WHY AND WHAT CAN
BE DONE.
NEXT, WE WILL HEAR FROM OUR
SUNDAY PANEL ABOUT THE TRAGEDY
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
>> IT WAS GREAT TO SEE THEM AT
THE SAME TIME WE HAD A LOT OF
PEOPLE WHO COULDN'T FIND THEIR
KIDS.
PERSONAL I HAVE A GOOD FRIEND
THAT LOST HER DAUGHTER.
SO IT'S VERY BITTER SWEET.
>> FOURTH GRADE BOY WHO GOT
OUT SAFELY EXPRESS GUILTY THE
ANGUISH OF ALL THE MOMS SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY.
IT'S TIME FOR SUNDAY GROUP.
BRIT HUME BRIT HUME.
CRYSTAL FROM THE "WEEKLY
STANDARD" AND LIZ OF THE
CHRISTIAN SCIENCE MONITOR.
A LIST OF SOME OF THE MASS
SHOOTINGS.
' 2012.
SCHOOL JULY 20TH.
AURORA COLORADO.
WHITE SPRIM MIST IN A SIKH
TEMPLE.
JACOB.
LANZA KILLS 27 PLUS HIMSELF.
IN FACT THERE WERE 1313 MASS
SHOOTINGS SO FAR THIS YEAR.
BRIT, WHAT IS GOING ON?
>> WE CERTAINLY WE DO YET,
THIS ONE.
DAY COMES UP AND I THINK THAN
ANY OF THE OTHERS BECAUSE OF
THE SCALE OF IT AND BECAUSE OF
VICTIMS WERE LITTLE CHILDREN.
AND SO I THINK LOOKING AT IT
FROM A WASHINGTON PERSPECTIVE,
POLITICALLY IMPACT OF IT IS
LIKELY TO BE GREATER.
THE HARD THING TO DO IN
COMMENTING ON REACTING TO THIS
IS THAT SO MUCH OF THE
INFORMATION THAT WE HAVE
GOTTEN SO FAR HAS TURNED OUT
TO BE DRAW ANY CONCLUSIONS.
SO MUCH WE KNOW AND IT WILL BE
A WHILE BEFORE IT'S POSSIBLE.
INTELLIGENT OBSERVATIONS.
WHAT KIND OF STEPS CAN BE
TAKEN TO PREVENT THIS.
>> NINA, PRESIDENT OBAMA
TALKED ABOUT TAKING MEEKFUL
ACTION.
BUT HE ALSO TALKED ABOUT
TAKING ACTION AFTER THE
SHOOTING OF GABRIEL GIFFORDS
IN JANUARY OF 2011 THAT KILLED
SIX AND WOUNDED 13 AND HE
NEVER DID.
DO YOU THINK, WE TALK ABOUT.
THIS THE IMPACT THE SOME
PEOPLE ARE COMPARING
EMOTIONALLY TO A 9/11 THAT
AFTER THE MASSACRE OF THESE
CHILDREN AND NOW RE-ELECTION.
THAT HE MIGHT ACTUALLY PUSH
FOR GUN CONTROL?
>> I THINK THIS IS A TIPPING
POINT.
HE SPOKE ON FRIDAY, NOT JUST
AS A -- NOT JUST AS A
PRESIDENT BUT AS A FATHER AND
I HAD JUST LEFT MY DAUGHTER'S
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL CONCERT AND
I THINK BACK TO THE SHOOTING
IN THE COLORADO MALL.
MY SONS, MY TEENAGE SONS WERE
SEEING THE DARK KNIGHT THAT
NIGHT.
MY NEPHEW LOST A FRIEND AND
ATTENDED THE VIRGINIA TECH.
KEEP IN MIND THIS WAS THE
SECOND WORSE SCHOOL SHOOTING,
VIRGINIA TECH WAS EVEN WORSE.
I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT FOR THE
PRESIDENT AT THIS POINT TO
TAKE A LOOK BE DONE IN A
BIPARTISAN WAY AND AGREE WITH
SENATOR LIEBERMAN IT HAS TO BE
COMMISSION, URGENT COMMISSION.
HAVE YOU GOT TO TAKE -- YOU
HAVE GOT TO LOOK AT HOW TO
TAKE THE WORD MASS OUT OF MASS
MURDER.
YOU KNOW, BODIES, 6-YEAR-OLD
BODIES WITH 3 TO 11 WULTS IN
THEM.
HAVE TO FIGURE OUT A WAY NOT
EASY, NOT GUN CONTROL.
I'M NOT ARGUING THAT.
WHEN YOU CAN GO ONLINE AND
ORDER A MAGAZINE WITH 100
ROUNDS OF AMMUNITION FOR $299,
SOMETHING'S WRONG.
I THINK IT HAS TO START THERE
IT ALSO HAS TO LOOK AT THE
WARNING THAT WERE IN PLACE IN
ALL OF THESE SITUATIONS.
MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES, PRIVACY
ISSUES.
THERE IS A LOT OF ISSUES THAT
GO INTO THIS.
I DO THINK GUN CONTROL HAS TO
BE PART OF IT.
>> BILL, LET'S LOOK AT THIS
FROM THE REPUBLICAN POINT OF
VIEW.
SHOULD REPUBLICANS CHANGE OR
MODIFY THEIR STRONG OPPOSITION
TO GUN CONTROL, ESPECIALLY NOT
THE RIGHT TO BEAR ARMS BUT
ESPECIALLY ON THIS QUESTION OF
THESE WEAPONS OF MASS
DESTRUCTION.
YOU KNOW, AS I SAY, THE
HANDGUN THAT COULD FIRE FIVE
BULLETS IN A SECOND.
THE MAGAZINES, 100 ROUNDS.
SHOULD REPUBLICANS CONSIDER
GIVING ON THAT ISSUE?
>> I THINK REPUBLICANS AND
EVERYONE ELSE SHOULD TAKE A
SERIOUS LOOK AT WHAT MIGHT
WORK.
I THINK THE SPEAKER COULD WELL
ASK THE REPUBLICAN CHAIRMAN OF
THE JUDICIARY COMMITTEE TO
HOLD HEARINGS.
HOLD SERIOUS HEARINGS ABOUT
WHAT WOULD WORK.
DON'T DO SOMETHING SYMBOLIC
LIKE THE ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN
WHICH DID NO GOOD END UP
EVAPORATING AND SUSTAINED
DEMOCRATIC WASN'T RESTORED
WHEN THE DEMOCRATS RESTORED
EVERYTHING IN 2009, 2010.
SO I'M TOTALLY OPEN TO HAVING
SERIOUS -- A LOT OF SOCIAL
SCIENCE RESEARCH ON GUN
CONTROL.
I DON'T THINK IT'S FAVORABLE
TO MOST EFFORTS OF GUN
CONTROL.
I THINK EVERYTHING HAS TO BE
ON THE TABLE TOO.
IS IT GUN FREE ZONES.
MAYBE HAVING SECURITY GUARDS
THAN HAVING DO BACKGROUND
CHECKS IN A CASE WHERE THE
PURCHASE OF THE GUNS IN THIS
CASE PASS BACKGROUND CHECK.
CONNECTICUT IS A PRETTY
LIBERAL STATE.
I BELIEVE THE DEMOCRATIC PARTY
CONTROLS ALL THE BRANCHES OF
GOVERNMENT IN CONNECTICUT.
THEY CHOSE NOT TO BAN THE
THINGS WE ARE TALKING ABOUT.
I GUESS.
THEY COULD HAVE.
COULDN'T THEY?
>> STATE LAWS ARE USELESS.
CAN YOU ORDER THINGS ONLINE
NOW.
YOU HAVE TO LOOK AT -- I'M
JUST SAYING LET'S HAVE AN
HONEST DEBATE AND PRIVACY
LAWS, MENTAL HEALTH.
I DO THINK THE REPUBLICAN
PARTY SHOULDN'T BE IN A
POSITION OF SAYING YOU CAN'T
EVEN DISCUSS.
THIS I THINK THE SPEAKER COULD
EASILY ASK CONTROL ONE HOUSE
OF CONGRESS, SENATOR REID
COULD THIS ON THE OTHER SIDE.
HAVE SIROUS HEARINGS ABOUT THE
LEGAL ISSUES AND THE PUBLIC
POLICY ISSUES.
>> Chris: YOU KNOW, LIZ, I'M
SURE THAT SOME OF OUR
LISTENERS LISTENED TO THIS
TALK ABOUT JOE LIEBERMAN
CALLING FOR A COMMISSION OR
BILL KRISTOL CALLING FOR
HEARINGS.
AND I DON'T MEAN THIS IN A
BELITTLING WAY.
THEY THINK WE HAVE HEARD THIS
ALL BEFORE.
THAT JUST MEANS WE WILL HAVE
SOME DOCUMENTS, WE'LL HAVE
SOME HEARINGS AND NOTHING WILL
HAPPEN.
AND MAYBE NOTHING SHOULD
BUT, YOU KNOW, PEOPLE WILL SIT
THERE AND SAY MORE OF THE
SAME.
>> AND THAT IS POSSIBLE.
I THINK I AGREE WITH NINA THAT
THIS FEELS A LITTLE BIT LIKE A
TIPPING POINT.
AND ONE OF THE PHRASES YOU
KEEP HEARING IS THAT PEOPLE
ARE FED UP.
THERE SEEMS TO BE THIS DESIRE
FOR ACTION.
NOT JUST A COMMISSION OR A
REPORT OR A DEBATE OR A
NATIONAL DEBATE.
THERE SEEMS TO BE A STRONGER
DESIRE FOR LET'S FIND SOME
CONCRETE STEPS MAYBE THAT WE
CAN TAKE RIGHT AWAY.
EVEN IF THEY MAKE ONLY A
SLIGHT DIFFERENCE.
MAYBE THAT WILL EFFECT IT IT I
ALSO WONDER IF THE POLITICS OF
THIS MIGHT CHANGE.
WE ARE SEEN, YOU KNOW, OVER
THE LAST FEW DECADES, GALLUP
HAS SHOWN SUPPORT FOR GUN
CONTROL HAS FALLEN OFF PRETTY
DRAMATICALLY.
YOU WONDER IF IN THE WAKE OF
THIS PAST ELECTION THE
DEMOCRATIC COALITION SEEMS TO
BE CHANGING SOMEWHAT.
YOU WONDER IF DEMOCRATIC
POLITICIANS MAY NOT SEE THIS
AS SUCH A THIRD RAIL ISSUE AS
THEY HAD AS YOU SAID WITH
LIEBERMAN AFTER THE 2000
ELECTION AND IN RECENT YEARS.
>> YOU KNOW, BRIT, ONE OF THE
THINGS THAT I VALUE MOST ABOUT
YOU IS WHEN EVERYBODY IS
RUSHING IN ONE DIRECTION, YOU
ARE A CONTRARIAN AND YOU SAY
WAIT A MINUTE.
>> WE DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
HERE.
REALLY.
WE DON'T.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
INSIDE THAT ELM.
WHO WE DON'T KNOW WHY FOR SURE
THIS WOMAN SEEMED COMPELLED TO
BUY ALL THESE WEAPONS IF
INDEED THAT'S WHAT HAPPENED.
WE DON'T KNOW MUCH ABOUT THIS
YOUNG MAN.
WE NEED TO KNOW ALL OF THAT
BEFORE WE MAKE -- START MAKING
ANY POLICY PREDICTIONS.
WE ALSO NEED TO FIND OUT AS
BEST WE CAN WHAT INFLUENCES
WITHIN THE CULTURE HAVE
CREATED THIS -- MAY HAVE
HELPED TO CREATE THIS WAVE OF
VIOLENCE.
PERHAPS A DECENTIZATION TO
YOU SEE IT ON THE SCREEN.
>> I WAS GOING TO SAY THERE IS
NO PERHAPS.
THERE HAS BEEN.
I SEE MY KIDS PLAYING THESE
GAMES WHERE THEY ARE SOLDIERS.
>> LOOK, I PLAYED A LOT OF
GUNS WHEN I WAS A KID.
SEE A LOT OF COWBOY WESTERNS.
>> Chris: IT'S DIFFERENT.
>> I DON'T DISAGREE WITH YOU.
THAT NEEDS TO BE PART OF IT.
MENTAL HEALTH COMPONENT AS
YELL.
THERE IS A LOT IN THIS.
IF THERE IS GOING TO BE
INVESTIGATION IT SHOULDN'T
FOCUS ON SINGLE ISSUE IT
SHOULD FOCUS ON ALL THE THINGS
THAT MAY HAVE CONTRIBUTED TO
THIS SO WE GET A BETTER
PICTURE OF IT.
>> Chris: WHAT ABOUT THE
AVERAGEMENT IF YOU HAVE THE
COMMISSIONS AND YOU HAVE THE
HEARINGS, NOTHING HAPPENS?
>> THAT'S NOT NECESSARILY THE
CASE.
YOU HAVE COMMISSIONS AND
HEARINGS AND SOMETIMES THINGS
DO HAPPEN.
WE HAD A BIG COMMISSION AFTER
9/11 AND THINGS DID HAPPEN.
SO, IT WILL DEPEND, I THINK ON
THE EXTINCT TO WHICH THE
POLITICAL ATMOSPHERE HAS BEEN
CHANGED BY THE HORROR AT THIS
KERR.
IT MAY WELL HAVE.
>> Chris: YOU GET THE FINAL
WORD.
>> I WAS GOING TO JUMP.
IN IT HAS TO BE SEEN IN THE
CONTEXT OF THIS INCIDENT AND
THE CONTEXT OF ALL THESE OTHER
INCIDENTS AND THE
COMMONALITIES ARE THERE WERE
WARNINGS.
IT INVOLVED MENTALLY UNSTABLE
PEOPLE AND SEMIAUTOMATIC
WEAPONS.
THAT'S WHAT YOU WILL FIND IS
COMMON IN ALL OF THESE
MURDERS.
>> A PERFECT STORM.
>> Chris: THANK YOU, PANEL.
SEE YOU NEXT WEEK.
DON'T FORGET TO SEE PANEL PLUS
GROUP PICKS UP WITH DISCUSSION
ON WEB SITE FOXNEWSSUNDAY.COM
AND POST THE VIDEO BEFORE NOON
EASTERN TIME AND MAKE SURE TO
FOLLOW US ON TWITTER AT "FOX
NEWS SUNDAY."
WE'LL BE BACK IN A MOMENT WITH
A TRIBUTE TO ACTS OF SACRIFICE
AND COURAGE IN THE FACE OF
EVIL.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
RED LOBSTER'S CRABFEST
ENDS SOON.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OURENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
...
>>.
>> Chris: TOO OFTEN WE LET
EVENTS LIKE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY BE DEFINED BY THE
SHOOTER.
THERE IS ANOTHER WAY TO LOOK AT
IT.
BRAVERY OF THE SCHOOL PRINCIPAL
THAT RAN TO THE GUNSHOTS GIVING
HER LIFE TO TRY TO PROTECT HER
STUDENTS.
FIRST GRADER THAT RAN OUT OF A
CLASSROOM DOOR BUT NOT BEFORE
GRABBING HIS FRIEND.
WE WANT TO LEAVE YOU THOSE
IMAGES AND MEMORIES OF OUR
STRENGTH AND GOODNESS STANDING
UP TO EVIL.
WE'LL SEE YOU NEXT FOX NEWS
SUNDAY.
>>> THE COMMUNITY HAS COME
TOGETHER, FIRST RESPONDERS HAVE
COME TOGETHER.
COUNSELORS, IT'S AMAZING THE
IMMENSE AMOUNT OF FAMILY THAT IS
SHOWN IN THE CITY OF NEWTOWN.
♪
>> IN THE COMING DAYS AND IN THE