>>Neil: IT IS A PARENTS' WORST
NIGHTMARE, A GUNMAN OPENING FIRE
ON A KINDERGARTEN CLASS IN
CONNECTICUT AT AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
27 ARE DEAD.
20 ARE CHILDREN.
SIX ADULTS.
AND THE SHOOTER.
WELCOME, WERES I AM NEIL CAVUTO.
TODAY, NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, IS
IF A STATE OF SHOCK BECAUSE THE
UNTHINKABLE HAPPENED.
A MASS SHOOTING AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
HERE IS WHAT WE KNOW.
THERE ARE CONFLICTING REPORTS
OVER THE EXACT IDENTITY OF THE
SHOOTER.
WE TOLD THE SUSPECT'S BROTHER IS
BEING QUESTIONED.
OFFICIALS SAY HIS MOTHER WAS
FOUND DEAD IN CONNECTICUT.
THE FATHER'S BODY WAS FOUND IN
NEW JERSEY.
THERE ARE SEPARATE REPORTS UP TO
FOUR WEAPONS POSSIBLY INVOLVED
INCLUDING A RIFLE AND TWO
AUTOMATIC WEAPONS.
THE PRESIDENT VISIBLY SHAKEN BY
TODAY'S ATTACKS.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF FIVE AND 10 YEARS
OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM, BIRTHDAYS,
GRADUATIONS, WEDDINGS, KIDS OF
THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FOLLOWING WERE ALSO
TEACHERS AND MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES TO HELP OUR
CHILDREN FULFILL THEIR DREAMS.
>>Neil: NOW THE LATEST FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
RICK?
Rick: THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT WAS HERE A SHORT
TIME AGO AND CALLED THIS A
TRAGEDY OF UNSPEAKABLE TERMS
THAT YOU CAN NEVER BE FULLY
PREPARED FOR.
REMEMBER, THIS HAPPENED OVER SIX
HOURS AGO.
THERE IS A LOT OF EVIDENCE STILL
BEING PROCESSED.
THE CRIME SCENE IS STILL VERY
ACTIVE.
OTHER SCENES ARE NOW
INVESTIGATED, INCLUDING THE HOME
OF SHOOTER'S MOVIE WHERE AN
ADULT BODY WAS FOUND AND OTHER
RESIDENTS IN NEW JERSEY WITH
CONFLICTING REPORTS OF THE
STATUS OF THE SHOOTER'S FATHER
AND CONFLICTING REPORTS ON THE
SHOOTER HIMSELF.
WHAT WE ARE TOLD AT THIS HOUR IS
THAT THE SHOOTER IS 20-YEAR-OLD
ADAM LANZA AND HIS 24-YEAR-OLD
BROTHER WAS TAKEN INTO CUSTODY
AND QUESTIONED BUT THAT RYAN AT
THIS POINT IS NOT A SUSPECT.
WE ARE TOLD THE SHOOTER WAS
ADAM, HE HAD TWO WEAPONS
INCLUDING AN ASSAULT RIFLE AND A
10 MILLIMETER GLOCK AND HE
ANSWERED THE SCHOOL WHERE THE
MORE WAS A TEACHER AND BEGAN
FIRING.
POLICE GOT 9-1-1 CALL.
LOCAL POLICE SHOWED UP AND
CALLED IN THE STATE POLICE.
UNLIKE COLUMBINE WHERE THE
OFFICERS WAITED OUTSIDE THE
HOSPITAL, IN THIS CASE THE
OFFICERS IMMEDIATELY ENTERED THE
SCHOOL, SEARCHING IF ADULTS AND
CHILDREN THEY COULD BRING OUT TO
SAFETY AND THAT IS EXACTLY WHAT
THEY D THEY WENT IN THAT SCHOOL,
THE POLICE SAY THEY FOUND TWO
ROOMS IN THE SCHOOL IN ONE AREA
OF THE SCHOOL WHERE THE VICTIMS
EVERYONE LOCATED.
20 CHILDREN TWO OF THEM
TRANSPORTED TO A LOCAL HOSPITAL
AND DIED IN THE HOSPITAL AND 18
CHILDREN FOUND DEAD INSIDE THE
SCHOOL ALONG WITH SIX ADULTS
INCLUDING THE SHOOTER AND THERE
IS ANOTHER ADULT THEY FOUND IN
ANOTHER LOCATION HERE IN SANDY
HOOK.
SO, A VERY, VERY DIFFICULT
SITUATION.
A CRIME SCENE THAT WILL TAKE
DAYS TO PROCESS AND A LOST
QUESTIONS REMAIN UNANSWERED.
WHAT WE ARE TOLD IS THE
SHOOTER'S MOTHER WAS A
KINDERGARTEN TEACHER AND THE
SHOOTER WENT TO THE MOTHER'S
CLASSROOM AND SHOT THE KIDS IN
THE CLASSROOM AS WELL AS FIVE
OTHER ADULTS IN THE SCHOOL AND
KILL -- SIX OTHER ADULTS IN THE
SCHOOL AND KILLED HIMSELF.
WE ARE CONTINUING TO GET
INFORMATION ON THIS AND PUTTING
IT TOGETHER.
>>Neil: THANK YOU.
IT IS 60 MILES EAST OF FORK
CITY, IN FAIRFAX COUNTY, ONE OF
THE RICHEST COUNTIES IN NEW
YORK.
IT LOOKS LIKE SOMETHING OUT OF
READER'S DIGEST.
A COMMUNITY AS IMMUNITY WOULD
SEEM TO VIOLENCE AS ANY
COMMUNITY IN AMERICA.
BUT TODAY FRONT AND CENTER THE
LATEST ACT OF VIOLENCE IN
AMERICA, THE SHOOTING, TODAY,
ARE THE SECOND BIGGEST ATTACK ON
AN AMERICAN EDUCATIONAL
INSTITUTION SINCE VIRGINIA TECH
IN 2007 WHEN 32 WERE KILLED.
FORMER HOMICIDE DETECTIVE, ROD,
WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF THIS?
>> WHAT I CAN TELL YOU AND THE
VIEWERS IS WHAT THE POLICE ARE
DOING.
WHAT WE WOULD DO IF AN
INVESTIGATION, HORRIFIC
INVESTIGATION LIKE THIS, TRYING
TO FIGURE OUT WHAT WAS THE
MOTIVE BEHIND THIS SUSPECT'S
ACTIONS.
WHY THE CHILDREN?
THAT IS THE QUESTION.
THE OTHER QUESTION AS
INVESTIGATORS, WHERE DID HE GET
THE WEAPONS IN WE WILL FIND THAT
OUT THE NEXT DAY OR TWO.
WHERE DID HE GET THE AMMUNITION?
WHY DID HE TARGET THIS SCHOOL?
THIS IS A VERY FLUID
INVESTIGATION AND THERE ARE
SEVERAL AGENCIES RIGHT NEW.
I GOT OFF THE PHONE WITH THE
CONTACT IN CONNECTICUT THAT
TELLS ME THAT THE FORENSIC
LABORATORY HAS BEEN CALLED IN.
THERE ARE SEVERAL AGENCIES
INVESTIGATING THIS CASE RIGHT
NOW AND WE ARE TRYING TO FIND
OUT WHY THIS SCHOOL, WHY THIS
SUSPECT, AND WHAT THE
CORRELATION IS BETWEEN THIS GUY
AND THE SCHOOL.
WE KNOW HIS MOTHER WORKED AT THE
SCHOOL BUT WHAT ABOUT THE OTHER
PEOPLE.
ALSO, WHETHER OR NOT THERE ARE
MORE VICTIMS.
THAT HAS NOT BEEN SAID WHETHER
THEY MAY OR MAY NOT FIND OTHER
VICTIMS.
SO THEY ARE INTERVIEWING FAMILY
MEMBERS OF THE SUSPECT AND THEY
ARE ALSO BEGINNING OUT WITH
SEARCH WARRANTS RIGHT NOW AS I
SPEAK INTO AREAS WHICH WE KNOW
THIS GUY HAS BEEN JUST TO MAKE
SURE THERE ARE NO OTHER VICTIMS.
>>Neil: WHEN THEY GO AND TREAT
THE SCHOOL AS A CRIME SCENE,
WHAT ARE THEY LOOKING FOR?
>>Guest: WHAT THEY ARE LOOKING
FOR SPECIFICALLY, AN EXCELLENT
QUESTION, WHAT TYPE OF QUESTION
DOES THIS GUY USE?
WHAT TIME OF AMMUNITION DID HE
USE?
DID HE TARGET ANY OF THE
CHILDREN OR THE ADULTS
SPECIFICALLY?
A LOST TIMES IN THESE SITUATIONS
AN INDIVIDUAL WILL START OUT
WITH ONE TARGET AND HE WILL WINE
UP IF HE HAS THE APPEAR IN
ADDITION SHOOTING SEVERAL PEOPLE
WE TRYING TO FIND OUT IF HE
TARGETS ONE.
SOMEBODY OR SOMETHING IGNITED
THIS GUY.
EITHER TODAY OR YESTERDAY.
IT SEEMS LIKE SOMEONE IGNITED
THIS GUY YESTERDAY BECAUSE IT
SEEMED LIKE IT WAS A MAPPED
SHOOTING BUT WHEN I TALK TO MY
SOURCES HE WAS READY.
I AM NOT SURE IF HE HAD THIS
PLANNED OUT OR WAS THIS A
RESPOND ATTENDOUS EVENT?
THOSE ARE THE QUESTIONS WE ARE
TRYING TO FIND OUT RIGHT NOW.
>> YOU KNOW, HIS BROTHER, RYAN,
WHO WAS ORIGINALLY IDENTIFIED AS
THE SHOOTER MAYBE BECAUSE ADAM
HAD SOMETHING INDICATING HE WAS
RYAN ON HIM, BUT, THAT BROTHER
IS NOW IN POLICE CUSTODY IN NEW
JERSEY.
WHAT ARE AUTHORITIES TRYING TO
GET OUT OF HIM IF HE WERE NOT AN
ACCOMPLICE, WHAT ARE THEY TRYING
TO LEARN?
>> IT IS NOT UNUSUAL FOR FAMILY
MEMBERS TO BE THOUGHT AS BEING A
PERSON THAT COMMITTED AN ACT
WHEN ANOTHER FAMILY MEMBER DID
IT.
THAT HAPPENS OFTEN.
THE ROPE THE POLICE ARE TALKING
TO HIS BROTHER IS BECAUSE THOSE
PEOPLE THAT ARE CLOSE TO THE
SHOOTER, THE CLOSEST TO THE
SHOOTER, WHETHER HE HAD A
GIRLFRIEND, OTHER FAMILY
MEMBERS, HIS BROTHER, COUSINS,
THOSE ARE THE FOLKS THAT THEY
WILL GET INFORMATION FROM AND
THEY TRYING TO GET AS MUCH
INFORMATION AS THEY CAN AS FAST
AS THEY CAN.
KEEP IN MIND, WE STILL DON'T
KNOW IF THERE ARE OTHER VICTIMS
OUT THERE SO THIS WILL WE
INTERVIEW EVERYONE AND ANYONE
ASSOCIATED WITH THIS SHOOTER, WE
WON'T HAVE THOSE ANSWERS.
OVER THE NEXT HOPEFULLY 12 TO 24
HOURS WE WILL HAVE MORE ANSWERS
COMING FORWARD.
>>Neil: IS THAT WHY YOU DON'T
REMOVE BODIES FROM A CRIME
SCENE?
>>Guest: YOU ARE RIGHT.
WE DON'T.
NOW ADAYS, I HAVE BEEN IF LAW
ENFORCEMENT A LONG-TERM WE USED
TO REMOVE BODIES QUICKER.
THERE IS NO NEED TO REMOVE
QUICKLY IF THERE ARE NO
SURVIVORS BECAUSE OF FORENSICS,
WE GET BETTER INFORMATION IF WE
LEAVE THE BODIES THERE AND LET
THE EXPERTS COME IN.
>> WHAT A HORRID CRIME SCENE.
WHEN YOU STEP BACK AND LOCK AT
THIS AND WE WILL GO IN MORE
DETAILS WITH PSYCHOLOGISTS AND
FOLKS LIKE THAT, PEOPLE TALK
ABOUT THE PICK UP IF VIOLENCE
WHETHER IT IS THE SHOPPING MALL
A COUPLE OF DAYS AGO OR AT THE
THEATER IN AURORA OR COLUMBINE
BEFORE THAT, AND JUST NOT IN
AMERICA WE HAVE SEEN SHOOTINGS,
HORRIBLE SHOOTINGS IN
SCANDINAVIA AND REPUBLIC OF
GEORGIA, IN FACT, IN
SCANDINAVIA, 50.
WHAT I AM ASKING, WHAT THE HECK
IS GOING ON?
>>Guest: WELL, HERE IS THE
REALITY.
LAW ENFORCEMENT KNOW THAT THE
SITUATIONS APPEAR TO BE
INCREASING AND THERE ARE A
NUMBER OF REASONS.
I WILL LEAVE THAT TO THE VIEWERS
DECIDE WHY THEY THING THEY ARE
INCREASING.
I AM HERE IN MINNESOTA TODAY
TEACHING A COURT JUST THIS
MORNING ON ACTIONS OF CHILDREN
IN A SCHOOL SYSTEM BECAUSE WE
REALIZE JUST TODAY I WAS
SPEAKING WHEN ONE OF THE
STUDENTS SAID THERE IS A
SHOOTING GOING ON IN
CONNECTICUT.
I AM NOT SURPRISED.
WE AS A NATION, WE HAVE TO COME
UP WITH A POLICY THAT ADDRESSES
THE MEMBERSHIP TALL ILL, NOT THE
GUNS BUT THE MENTAL MILLNESS AND
GET TO THE BOTTOM OF IT.
HOW LONG HAVE WE BEEN TALKING
ABOUT THERE?
FOR YEARS.
WE KNOW THIS IS A REALITY.
WE HAVE TO DEAL WITH IT.
>>Neil: WE HAVE TO STOP
MEETING LIKE THIS BUT THANK YOU
FOR YOUR EXPERTISE.
NOW A PSYCHOLOGIST, DOCTOR, WHY
SO MUCH OF THERE AND WHY WE ARE
SEEING MORE THIS OR APPEAR TO.
ARE WE?
>>Guest: IT SURE SEEMS LIKE
IT.
THIS IS AS BAD AS IT GETS.
THE CHILDREN, MY OFFICE THIS
MORNING HAS BEEN OVERWHELM BY
CALLS FROM PARENTS IN LOS
ANGELES TRAUMAIZED BY THIS
BECAUSE WE ALL IDENTIFY WITH THE
KIDS.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT THE NUMBERS, I
HAVE TO SAY IT IS SO MANY
FACTORS.
YOU HAVE THE BREAKDOWN OF
VALUES.
STRUCTURES THAT HELD US
TOGETHER.
MORALLY, SPIRITUALLY, TOO MANY
FACTORS TO TALK ABOUT.
THE OFFICERS' POINT WAS
IMPORTANT, WHEN PEOPLE ARE MORE
EDUCATED ABOUT WHAT TO LOOK FOR
IN THE MENTALLY ILL AND THOSE
WHO HAVE DARK LIKES WHERE YOU
SEE THE CLUES WHICH WILL
PROBABLY EMERGE, THE MORE
AWARENESS EVERYONE GETS, WE CAN
ALL BE HELPED BY THAT.
>>Neil: WHY KIDS, DOCTOR, WHEN
THESE INCIDENTS HAPPEN?
MOST THESE WERE KINDERGARTENERS.
>>Guest: WE WERE TALKING ABOUT
THAT ALL MORNING.
IN SOME WAYS IT IS ONE OF THOSE
UNANSWERABLES.
YOU CAN ALWAYS SEE A PATH.
THERE IS MENTAL ILLNESS THAT CAN
CAUSE THINGS LIKE THIS.
THERE IS HORRIBLE LIFE STORIES
BUT THE REALITY IS NOT EVERYONE
WHO IS MENTALLY ILL COMMITS AN
ACT LIKE THIS.
NOT EVERYONE ABUSED AS A CHILD
DOES THIS.
THIS IS A LINE OF THE HEART OR
THE SOUL OR THEIR SPIRIT THAT
SOME PEOPLE GO ONE WAY AND
OTHERS GO THE OTHER.
THE BIG THING IS WE DO KNOW THE
GREAT THEMES OF ISOLATION AND
POWERLESSNESS IN INDIVIDUALS'
LIKES SOW THIS AND WE DO AS PAST
WE CAN IN SPOTTING THAT AND
TRYING TO END THEM.
IF SOMETHING LOOKS YEAR, CALL
SOMEONE.
>> DOCTOR, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> ON THE DAY YOU CANNOT MAKE
SENSE OF STUFF, MANY OF THE
KINDERGARTENERS AND OTHER YOUNG
KIDS WHO WERE KILLED IN THE
TRAGEDY WERE PARTICIPATING IN
THE SCHOOL'S ANNUAL HOLIDAY
CHRISTMAS PERFORMANCE AND THEY
ARE ALL DEAD.
HAVING YOU SHIP MY GIFTS
COULDN'T BE EASIER.
WELL, HAVING A TON OF LOCATIONS
DOESN'T HURT.
AND A SANTA TO BOOT!
[ chuckles ]
RIGHT, BABY.
OH, SIR.
THAT IS A CUSTOMER.
OH...SORRY ABOUT THAT.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
FEDEX OFFICE.
Neural speeds
increasing to 4G LTE.
Brain upgrading to a quad-core
processor.
Predictive intelligence
with Google Now complete.
Introducing DROID DNA by HTC.
It's not an upgrade
to your phone.
It's an upgrade to yourself.
>>Neil: WE ARE GETTING WORD
OF A HORRENDOUS SCHOOL SHOOTING
AND YOU HER THE ALLEGED
SHOOTER'S MOTHER AND FATHER WERE
KILLED.
THE FATHER COULD BE VERY MUCH
ALIVE.
WE WILL KEEP YOU POSTED.
WE WANT TO LET YOU KNOW IN 30
MINUTES CUT ACCOUNT LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS ARE GOING
TO UPDATE THE MEDIA ON THE
LATEST.
WE KNOW AT THIS POINT OF 27 DEAD
IN CONNECTICUT, 18 CHILDREN,
LARGELY KINDERGARTENERS KILLED.
TWO ADDITIONAL CHILDREN WERE
TRANSPORTED TO DANBURY HOSPITAL
LATER PRONOUNCED DEAD.
SEX ADULTS INCLUDING THE
SCHOOL'S PRINCIPAL DEAD AT THE
SCENE.
THE SHOOTER IS DEAD, AS WELL.
SEPARATELY, AN ADULT DEAD.
THAT IS, THE ASSAILANT'S MOTHER
IS DEAD BUT, AGAIN, THE REPORTS
THAT THE FATHER HAD BEEN KILLED
IN NEW JERSEY MAY NOT BE
ACCURATE.
REPORTS ARE THAT THE FATHER IS
MUCH ALIVE.
NOW STEPPING BACK TO GET A SENSE
FROM FORMER CITY MAYOR GIULIANI.
MAYOR, SO MUCH TO PUT TOGETHER.
>>Guest: THIS IS HORRENDOUS
AND SOMETHING IT IS HARD TO KEEP
YOUR EMOTIONS IN CHECK.
ALL OF US WHO ARE PARENTS, A
NIGHTMARE YOU LIVE THROUGH, A
QUIET COMMUNITY, SEMI RURAL
COMMUNITY, NEAR THE FEDERAL
PRISON THAT I KNOW WELL, DANBURY
PRISON.
THIS HAS TO BE A TOTAL COMPLETE
TRAUMATIC BLOW TO THE COMMUNITY.
YOU WILL NOT GET EASY ANSWERS,
THERE ARE IN EASY ANSWERS.
ANYONE WHO TRIES TO PRESENT EASY
18S IS IGNORING THE PROBLEM AND
TO EXAMINE WHY IT HAPPENED, IS
IT HAPPENING MORE FREQUENTLY,
CAN WE REDUCE IT?
EVERYONE HAS TO BE ON THE TABLE,
YOU CANNOT BE AN ADVOCATE OR ONE
SOCIAL VIEW OR POLITICAL VIEW OR
THE OTHER.
IS LIFE DEEP IN THE HUMAN
PERSONALITY, THE FACTORS THAT
INDICATE THIS, SCIENCE HAS NOT
FIGURED OUT YET, WE CANNOT
PREDICT THIS, YOU CANNOT SEE IT
WITH ANY KIND OF CERTITUDE BUT
WE HAVE TO LOOK AT IF THERE ARE
BETTER WAYS TO PROTECT PREDICT
IT AND BETTER WAYS TO SCHOOL THE
SCHOOLS.
HE WALKED IN AT LEAST IN ONE
CASE WITH A LARGE WEAPON.
HOW DID THAT HAPPEN?
CAN YOU SECURE AGAINST THIS IN
WHAT DO WE DO ABOUT WEAPONS?
WE SHOULD HAVE A NONPOLITICAL
HUMBLE DISCUSSION.
>>Neil: I HEAR YOU.
>>Guest: EVERYTHING SHOULD BE
ON THE TABLE AND EVERYONE SHOULD
HAVE SOME HUMILITY THAT THEY
DON'T HAVE THE ANTIS.
>>Neil: WHAT ABOUT, REMEMBER
AFTER COLUMBINE THEY PUT METAL
DETECTORS IN A LOT OF SCHOOLS.
WE STILL HAD SHOOTING.
BUT IT DIDN'T STOP VIRGINIA
TECH.
>>Guest: HERE IS THE TRUTH.
YOU COULD HAVE HAD PERFECT
SECURITY FOR THE SCHOOL AND THE
CHILDREN WOULD BE ALIVE.
BUT ANOTHER GROUP OF CHILDREN
WOULD BE DEAD.
A PERSONALITY LIKE THIS, IT
SEEMS TO ME, WILL KILL.
IF IT 90 THE KIDS IN THE SCHOOL,
IT COULD BE SOMEONE ELSE.
THERE ARE A LOT OF FACTORS SO
THERE IS NOT A SIMPLE SOLUTION
AND YOU CANNOT SAY JUST SECURE
THE SCHOOLS.
THEN IT WILL HAPPEN IN A
SHOPPING CENTER.
YOU CANNOT SAY, IT IS GUNS.
MORE PEOPLE GOT SKILLED IN
SCANDINAVIA, THE TIGHTEST GUN
LAWS.
IT IS NOT JUST HUMAN BEHAVIOR
BECAUSE WE CANNOT PREDICT HUMAN
BEHAVIOR.
WHAT I WOULD LIKE TO SEE IS FOR
THIS COUNTRY TO DISCUSS ALL OF
THIS WITH EVERYONE LAYING ASIDE
THEIR PREJUDICE AND WHAT THEY
ARE COMMITTED TO THE MOST AND
HAVING HUMILITY.
>>Neil: IF METAL DETECTORS IF
SOMEONE IS GOING TO KILL A LOT
OF PEOPLE AND THAT IS THEIR
INTENT THEY WILL GO THROUGH
THAT.
>>Guest: THERE ARE BETTER
ANSWERS.
THERE ARE APPROACHES TO THIS AND
IF ALL OF US REALIZE THE
ENORMITY OF THIS, THE WAY WE DID
SEPTEMBER 11TH WHERE EVERYONE
PUT ASIDE THEIR USUAL POLITICAL
IDEAS AND TRIED TO SEEK A BETTER
ANSWER, MAYBE WE CAN REDUCE
THIS.
FINALLY, OUR HEARTS HAVE TO GO
OUT TO THE PARENTS.
THESE PEOPLE BEING DEALT A BLOW
NO ONE SHOULD HAVE TO GO TO.
>>Neil: NOBODY.
BEGIN.
TOMATO,
OBVIOUSLY.
HAHA. THERE'S MORE
THAN THAT THOUGH,
THERE'S A KICK TO IT.
WAHLALALALALLALA!
SMOOTH, BUT CRISP.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE DRINKING
A FOOD THAT'S A DRINK,
OR A DRINK THAT'S A FOOD,
WOOOOOH!
[ Male Announcer ] TASTE IT
AND DESCRIBE THE INDESCRIBABLE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
♪
MANY HOT DOGS
ARE WITHIN YOU.
TRY PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO,
IT'S THE POWER OF PEPTO,
BUT IT FITS IN YOUR POCKET.
NOW TELL THE WORLD
DANIEL...
OF PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO.
>> THIS IS IN NEW JERSEY, WHERE
THERE IS SOME ADDED ENTRY HERE,
THE HOME OF RYAN LANZA HE IS THE
24-YEAR-OLD OLDER BROTHER ADAM
LANZA WHO IS THE MAN REPORTEDLY
BEHIND THE SHOOTINGS WHO, WELL,
IS NOT DEAD.
EITHER KILLED HIMSELF OR WAS
KILLED BY AUTHORITIES.
BUT THEY TRYING TO FIND OUT WHAT
THEY CAN, NOT ONLY FROM RYAN
LANZA HIMSELF, WHAT HE MIGHT
KNOW ABOUT HIS BROTHER, OR
WHETHER THERE WOULD BE ANYTHING
TO INCRIMINATE EITHER RYAN OR
HIS BROTHER AT THAT LOCALE.
TRACE HAS THE VERY LATEST.
TRACE?
>> LET ME POINT YOU TO THE
PICTURE ON THE SCREEN.
NOW WE ARE TOLD THAT THE FATHER
REPORTEDLY WAS SAID TO BE KILLED
INSIDE THE HOUSE AND NOW
AUTHORITIES SAYING, NO, THE
FATHER IS ALIVE BUT THERE IS
SOMEONE WHO WAS SHOT AND KILLED
INSIDE THAT HOUSE BUT RYAN LANZA
WOULD WAS THOUGHT TO BE THE
ORIGINAL SHOOTER IS VERY MUCH
ALIVE.
EVEN AUTHORITIES ADMITTED THEY
WERE CONFUSED BUT NOW THEY HAVE
SAID WHAT HAPPENED IS, THEY
SWITCHED THE NAMES.
IN FACT, 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA
IS THE SHOOTER.
NOW, SOMEONE WAS KILLED IN NEW
JERSEY.
WE KNOW THAT.
AND THE MOTHER WAS SHOT AND
KILLED IF HER HOME IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, A TEACHER AT THE
SCHOOL.
SHE WAS SHOT AND KILLED AND
THERE ARE REPORTS THAT THE
WEAPONS THAT WERE USED IN THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING WERE REGISTERED
TO THE MOTHER.
POLICE SAY THAT IS WHEN THE
20-YEAR OLD ADAM LANZA WANT TO
THE SCHOOL, SOME WITNESSES SAY
HE MAY OR MAY NOT BE
DEVELOPMENTALLY DISABLED AND
WENT TO THE SCHOOL AND WAS
BUZZED IN THE FRONT DOOR.
THE SCHOOL WAS ON LOCKDOWN.
HE WAS BUZZED IN WITH THESE
WEAPONS AND HE WALKED IN THE
OFFICE AND OPENED FIRE GOING
AFTER THE PRINCIPAL.
AND THE PSYCHOLOGIST.
AND OTHERS IN THAT OFFICE.
IT WAS DURING MORNING
ANNOUNCEMENTS SO WHAT HAPPENED
WHILE THE ANNOUNCEMENTS WERE
BEING MADE THE REST OF THE
SCHOOL, THE STUDENTS AND THE
TEACHERS COULD HEAR THE VIOLENCE
AND SHOTS OVER THE SCHOOL
INTERCOM AND THE SHOOTER WENT TO
A CLASSROOM AND OPENED FIRE
TARGETING THE KIDS.
WE KNOW THE DEATH TOLL IS
DEPARTMENT CHILDREN AND SEX
ADULTS.
THE SHOOTER THEN TURNED THE GUN
ON HIMSELF THE THEY HAVE NOT
SAID WHY THE STUDENTS MAY HAVE
BEEN TARGETED AND THEY DO NOT
KNOW WHAT THE EXACT BREAKDOWN
IS, THE NUMBERS ARE CONFUSING IN
THE EARLY GOING BUT WE HAVE
GOTTEN TO THE BOTTOM OF THE
SHOOTER BEING 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM
LANZA.
RYAN IS BEING QUESTIONED.
WE DO NOT KNOW THE FATHER IS
INVOLVED IN THIS AT ALL BUT HE
IS ALIVE.
SOMEONE IS DEAD IN HOBOKEN, NEW
JERSEY, AND NOW WE HEAR THE
GIRLFRIEND OF RYAN LANZA IS
MISSING TO ADD ANOTHER TWIST TO
THIS.
>>Neil: THANK YOU, TRACE.
ALSO, CORRECTING SOMETHING I
SAID EARLIER, THERE WERE SEMI
AUTOMATIC WEAPONS FOUND AT THE
SCENE, NOT AUTOMATIC WEAPONS.
THAT WAS HIGH DAD AND THEY WROTE
IT THAT WAY AND I SAID AUTOMATIC
BUT THEY WERE SEMI-AUTOMATIC
WEAPONS SO MY APOLOGIES.
WHAT DO WE MAKE OF THAT?
>>Guest: IT IS A VERY COMMON
MISNOMER BECAUSE THE
SEMI-AUTOMATICS ARE SO FAST WE
ARE CUTTING HAIRS.
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT TWO ASSAULT
RIFLES, BRA -- BRUTAL WEAPONS.
HE WAS LOADED FOR MASS KILLING.
HE WAS VERY SUCCESSFUL.
>>Neil: THIS WAS CLEARLY IN
YOUR EYES PREMEDITATEED,
PREEXAMINED, PREIN THE OUT.
>>Guest: WELL-THOUGHT-OUT TO
MAKE CERTAIN HE HAD THE
BULLET-PROOF VEST ON, ON THE
OUTSIDE CHANCE AS WE TALKED AT
THE HOMICIDE IN THE MALL IN
OREGON, THAT ONE COULD BE ARMED
THAT COULD SHOOT AT HIM THE HE
WANTED TO PROTECT HIMSELF SO HE
COULD FINISH THIS BIZARRE
TWISTED MISSION.
THAT IS SERIOUS WEAPONS HE
BROUGHT IN.
>>Neil: IN SOME OF THE SCHOOL
INCIDENTS I WILL TAKE VIRGINIA
TECH OUT OF IT, AND COLLEGE
KIDS, BUT IN THESE INCIDENTS AND
NOT EVEN IN THE UNITED STATES
BUT IT HAPPENED ABROAD WHERE
THERE ARE VERY TOUGH GUN LAWS
AND WHY WANT TO GET IF THAT
DEBATE, BUT, WHY KIDS IN WHY
TARGET KIDS?
>>Guest: I TALKED TO THE
MAYOR, THE SAME THING CAME UP
AND HE BROUGHT UP A GREAT POINT.
THERE IS JUST, SPECULATION, THAT
SUCH EXTRAORDINARY
SUGGESTIBILITY THAT IS
BOMBARDING THEM EVERY SECOND
WITH THE WAY SOCIETY HAS EVOLVED
IN THE LAST 15 YEARS IN
TEMPERATURES OF THE MEDICINIA,
THAT MAYBE IT HAS DIMINISH THE
OR MINIMIZED IT, THE VIOLENCE,
WHERE IT IS ALMOST LIKE A VIDEO
GAME.
I THEORIZE THAT.
I AM IN THIS BUSINESS 30 YEARS
AND MY VERY STRONG CONVICTION,
IT IS MIGHT THEIR STUFF.
>>Neil: HE WIPED OUT ALMOST AN
ENTIRE CLASS AT A MINIMUM
REPORTEDLY THESE WERE STUDENTS
OF HIS MOTHER.
>>Guest: CORRECT.
>>Neil: WHAT DO YOU DO TO
PREVENT THAT IN THE FUTURE?
WHEN WE COVERED THE MALL
SHOOTING, YOU SAID MAYBE WE ARM
THE SECURITY GUARDS.
WHAT DO YOU DO IN SCHOOL?
>>Guest: WE BRING SCHOOL
SECURITY AT FIVE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOLS, 50 MILES FROM HERE.
A MIDDLE SCHOOL.
ALSO, ONE HIGH SCHOOL.
WE TOOK OVER THIS ASSIGNMENT WE
CHANGED THE FANS.
WE PUT IN NYPD POLICE CAPTAIN IN
CHARGE AND ALL ARMED EX-NYPD
HERE.
THE INTERESTING THING IS THE
PROBLEMS ARE GENERALLY AT THE
SCHOOLS AT THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
BECAUSE OF CUSTODY CASES AND
BIOLOGICAL PARENTS AND THAT IS
WHERE THE CROWE WILL DOOR.
THEY HAD A PROTOCOL IN PLACE A
BUZZER, VISITOR BUZZING IN
SYSTEM.
THAT DOESN'T WORK.
>>Neil: BUT IF SOMEONE IS
INTENT AND YOU JUST GO IN THERE
WITH GUNS BLAZING NOTHING WILL
HAVE A SHORT LASTING EFFECT.
>>Guest: I AGREE.
THE FACT IS THOSE ARE GIGANTIC
RIFLES.
THEY CAME IN THE BUILDING, ONE
GUY, WITH TWO VERY LARGE RIFLES.
YOU CAN HIDE THE HANDGUNS.
IT COULD HAVE BEEN STOPPED BY
THE APPROPRIATE SECURITY.
FORGET THE METAL DETECTOR,
SOMEONE WHO IS ARMED AND TRAINED
WITH THE EXPERIENCE TO STOP THEM
DEAD IN HIS TRACKS, LET HIM GO
TO THE MAKER AND LITTLE THE
KINDERGARTEN KIDS GO TO MILK AND
COOKIES.
>>Neil: THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WE DO KNOW THAT 20 CHILDREN ARE
NOT GOING TO GO FOR MILK AND
COOKIES.
ARE NOT GOING TO ENEYE
CHRISTMAS.
THEIR FAMILIES ARE NOT, EITHER.
FOR A TOWN THAT WAS PART OF A
COMMUNITY AS RICH AS ALL GET
OUT, IN A COUNTY AMONG THE MOST
PRIZED IN THE NATION, IT
HAPPENED.
AGAIN.
WE ARE WAITING TO HEAR FROM
LOCAL AUTHORITIES HOW IT WENT
DOWN.
HI. I'M HENRY WINKLER.
AND I'M HERE TO TELL HOMEOWNERS
THAT ARE 62 AND OLDER
ABOUT A GREAT WAY
TO LIVE A BETTER RETIREMENT.
IT'S CALLED A REVERSE MORTGAGE.
[ Male Announcer ]
CALL RIGHT NOW
TO RECEIVE YOUR FREE
DVD AND BOOKLET
WITH NO
OBLIGATION.
IT ANSWERS QUESTIONS LIKE
HOW A REVERSE MORTGAGE WORKS,
HOW MUCH YOU QUALIFY FOR,
THE WAYS TO RECEIVE YOUR MONEY,
AND MORE.
PLUS, WHEN
YOU CALL NOW,
YOU'LL GET THIS MAGNIFIER
WITH L.E.D. LIGHT
ABSOLUTELY FREE.
WHEN YOU CALL THE EXPERTS
AT One Reverse Mortgage TODAY,
YOU'LL LEARN THE BENEFITS
OF A GOVERNMENT-INSURED
REVERSE MORTGAGE.
IT WILL ELIMINATE
YOUR MONTHLY MORTGAGE PAYMENTS
AND GIVE YOU TAX-FREE CASH
FROM THE EQUITY IN YOUR HOME.
AND HERE'S THE BEST PART --
YOU STILL OWN YOUR HOME.
TAKE CONTROL
OF YOUR RETIREMENT TODAY.
♪
>>Neil: A TENTATIVE TIMELINE
ON TODAY'S HORRIFIC EVENTS IN
CONNECTICUT ARE TO BE BELIEVED
IT ALL STARTED WITH THE SHOOTER
HAVING A MAJOR BEEF
MOTHER AND KILLING HER.
WE GO TO SANDY HOOK,
CONNECTICUT, WHERE MOLLY HAS
MORE ON THAT PART OF THE STORY
THAT TRIGGERED THE REST OF THE
DEVELOPMENTS.
MOLLY?
>>Reporter: YES, WE ARE AT A
SECONDARY CRIME SCENE.
THE SCHOOL IS WHERE MOST OF THE
ACTIVITY THROUGHOUT THE DAY HAS
OCCURRED.
THIS IS THE AREA WHERE THE
MOTHER LIVED, NANCY IS BELIEVED
TO BE A VICTIM, THAT DIED IN THE
HORRIFIC SLEW OF ACTIVITY.
THIS IS UPPER MIDDLE-CLASS
NEIGHBOR A QUIET NEIGHBORHOOD,
PARTICULARLY TODAY.
THEY STILL HAVE THE STREET
SECURED.
NO ONE IS ALLOWED TO GET DOWN TO
THE HOME WHERE THE SCENE IS.
THERE IS, THAT IS WHERE ONE OF
THE BODIES WAS FOUND, A BODY HAS
BEEN FOUND AT THIS LOCATION AND
AUTHORITIES ARE NOT SAYING WHO
IT IS, BUT OFFICIALS ARE SAYING
THAT NANCY HAS PASSED AWAY
THROUGHOUT THE COURSE OF THE
DAY.
>>Neil: MOLLY LINE, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
AND PEGGY'S DAUGHTER, MARJORIE,
SURVIVED COLUMN BIN SHOOTING
THAT ELECTRIFIED THE NATION, OUR
FIRST LARGE AWAKENING OF
LARGE-SCALE VIOLENCE AT A
SCHOOL.
PEGGY, HOW ARE YOU DOING?
>>Guest: WELL, THIS IS A REAL
HARD DAY FOR US, OUR HEARTS ARE
BROKEN FOR THESE PEOPLE.
THEY WERE JUST BABIES.
>>Neil: YOUR DAUGHTER SURVIVED
THE COLUMNBINE SHOOTING.
>>Guest: SHE STRUGGLES TO THIS
DAY.
IT WAS TERRIBLE FOR OUR FAMILY
AND A LOT OF THOSE KIDS ALTHOUGH
THEY WERE OLDER DID NOT SURVIVE
WELL.
MY OWN DAUGHTER DROPPED OUT OF
HIGH SCHOOL AFTER THAT.
>>Neil: HOW OLD WAS SHE?
>>Guest: SHE WAS 16.
>>Neil: NOW, A LOT OF THE
VICTIMS, MANY OF THE VICTIMS
WERE KINDERGARTENERS SO THAT
MAKES THEM FIVE OR SIX.
SOME WERE OLDER, WE UNDERSTAND.
WE DO NUT HAVE A BREAK DOWN.
DIFFERENT FOR THEM?
WHAT DO YOU THINK...YOUR
DAUGHTER'S EXPERIENCE, WHAT ARE
THEIR FAMILY MEMBERS HAVE TO
LACK OUT FOR?
>>Guest: WELL, THEY HAVE A
LONG ROAD AHEAD OF THEM AND THEY
SHOULD SEEK HELP FOR THEIR OWN
SELVES AND THEIR CHILDREN AS
SOON AS POSSIBLE BECAUSE I KNOW
FROM MY OWN SITUATION, I DIDN'T
REALIZE IT WOULD BE SUCH A LONG
ROAD.
THE REAL NIGHTMARE IS AFTER ALL
THE DUST SETTLES.
MY CHILD HAD NIGHTMARES,
FLASHBACKS, HER BEST FRIEND
KILLED HERSELF, THERE WAS A LOT
OF TRAGEDY AFTER THE COLUMBINE
SHOOTING AND WHEN THERE IS A
SHOOTING WE HEAR IN LITTLETON,
IT ALL COMES BACK.
>>Neil: HOW IS SHE DOING NOW?
>>Guest: SHE IS ABLE TO IT IS
IN A CLASSROOM BUT IT TOOK MANY
YEARS.
MANY YEARS.
SHE IS VERY AFFECTED TODAY BY
ALL OF THIS.
>>Neil: AMAZING.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YOU CAN JUST IMAGINE ALL THE
PARENTS WHO ARE GOING TO GO
THROUGH THAT, PARENTS OF MUCH
YOUNG ARE CHILDREN, MORE
IMPRESSIONABLE CHILDREN,
CHILDREN WHO SHOULD NOT BE
SEEING ANYTHING LIKE THIS AT
THIS TIME OF CAREER NO LESS, TO
FORMER ARKANSAS GOVERNOR, MIKE
HUCKABEE.
I WILL TRY TO TAP THE REACHER IN
YOU THE MAN OF GOD IN YOU WHO
CAN HELP US WITH THIS.
>>Governor Huckabee: THERE
IS NO HUMAN RATIONALE OR
EXPLANATION THE I WAS GOVERNOR
IN 1998 ON MARCH 31 WHEN THE
JONES BOTHER SCHOOL SHOOTINGS
HAPPENED AND IT IS ONE THOSE
DAYS I START RELIVING ALL OVER
AGAIN TODAY.
WHEN I HEAR THAT MOTHER TALK ONE
OF THE THINGS PEOPLE WILL NOT
FULLY COMPREHEND EVERY
TELEVISION CAMERA IN THE WORLD
WILL DESCEND UPON NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, OVER THE WEEKEND
AND THE NEXT SEVERAL DAYS AND
THEY WILL ALL LEAVE AND COVER
SOMETHING ELSE.
ALL THESE PEOPLE WILL STILL HAVE
THE SCARS, EMOTIONALLY AND MANY
THEM PHYSICALLY, IF YEARS TO
COME.
RIGHT NOW, WHAT IS VERY HARMFUL
IS SO MUCH ATTENTION BUT SO
LITTLE VALID INFORMATION.
IT WAS SO FRUSTRATING TO ME AND
OTHER OFFICIALS BECAUSE SO MANY
PEOPLE WERE SPECULATING WHAT
HAPPENED, WHO DID IT, WHY DID
THEY DO IT, AND WE DON'T KNOW
THOSE THINGS.
I DO BELIEVE THAT ONE OF THE
MOST IMPORTANT THINGS TO DO AT
THIS POINT IS TO TAKE IT VERY,
VERY CALMLY, AND SLOWLY, BUT THE
BIGGEST AFTERMATH OF SOMETHING
LIKE THIS, PEOPLE ARE GOING TO
LOOK FOR, OKAY, WHY DID IT
HAPPEN?
THE ANSWER IS INEXPLICABLE.
WHAT DO WE DO TO STOP IT IN YOU
CAN TAKE CERTAIN MEASURES AND I
THINK YOUR PREVIOUS GUEST HAD A
LOT OF GREAT IDEAS WHICH IS VERY
IMPORTANT.
ULTIMATELY YOU CAN TAKE EVERY
GUN AWAY IN AMERICA CAN SOMEONE
WILL USE A BOMB WHEN SOMEONE HAS
AN INTENT TO DO INCREDIBLE
DAMAGE THEY WILL FIND A WAY.
IN THE CASE OF JONESBORO, AN 11
AND 12-YEAR-OLD KIDS WHO GUNNED
DOWN THEIR CLASSMATES AND
TEACHERS AFTER THEY HAD GOT THEM
IN A SCHOOL YARD BY SETTING OFF
A FIRE ALARM WHERE THEY WERE
TRAPPED IN A FENCED AREA AND
COULD NOT GET BACK IN.
THEY WERE SITTING DUCKS.
THE QUESTION, HOW CAN AN 11 AND
TELEPHONE-YEAR-OLD DO THIS?
NO ONE CAN UNDERSTAND HOW THAT
CAN HAPPEN AND PEOPLE WILL WANT
TO PASS NEW LAWS BUT UNLESS YOU
CHANGE PEOPLE'S HEARTS OR
TRANSITION TO THE PASTOR SIDE,
THIS IS A HEART ISSUE.
LAWS DON'T CHANGE THIS.
>>Neil: PEOPLE ASK AFTER
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS, HOW COULD
GOD LET THIS HAPPEN.
>>Guest: IT IS AN INTERESTING
THING.
WE ASK WHY THERE IS VIOLENCE IN
OUR SCHOOLS BUT WE REMOVE GOD
FROM OUR SCHOOLS.
SHOULD WE BE SO SURPRISED
SCHOOLS WOULD BECOME A PLACE OF
CAN -- CARNAGE?
WE MAKE IT A PLACE WHERE WE DO
NOT WANT TO TALK ABOUT LIFE AND
WHAT RESPONSIBILITY MEANS,
ACCOUNTABILITY, WE WILL NOT JUST
BE ACCOUNTABLE FOR THE POLICE
BUT WE STAND ONE DAY BEFORE A
HOLY GOD IN JUDGMENT.
IF WE DON'T BELIEVE THAT, WE
DON'T FEAR THAT.
WHEN PEOPLE SAY, WHY DID GOD LET
IT HAPPEN, GOD WASN'T ARMED.
HE DIDN'T GO TO THE SCHOOL.
GOD WILL BE THERE IN THE FORM OF
A LOT PEOPLE WITH HUGS AND
THERAPY AND A LOT OF WAYS IN
WHICH HE WILL BE INVOLVED IN THE
AFTERMATH.
MAYBE WE OUGHT TO LET HIM IN ON
THE FRONT END AND WE WOULD NOT
HAVE TO CALL HIM TO SHOW UP WHEN
ALL IS SAID AND DONE AT THE BACK
END.
>>Neil: WE ARE STATE WAITING
TO HEAR FROM AUTHORITIES ON THE
SCENE, THE VERY LATEST NEWS ON
THE TRAGEDY THAT NOW RANKS
SECOND TO THE VIRGINIA TECH
KILLINGS BACK FIVE YEARS AGO, 32
WERE DEAD THEN.
27 DEAD TODAY.
..
[ woman ] WE KNEW IT WAS GONNA
BE BAD, BUT NEVER LIKE THIS.
THE RED CROSS WAS DOWN HERE
ALL THE TIME.
[ man ]
THEY'VE GIVEN US A LOT OF HEART.
IN TIMES OF NEED, THEY'RE THERE.
♪
[ Kerry ] MY DAD WAS WATCHING
HIS HOUSE BURN.
HE TURNED AROUND,
AND ALL OF A SUDDEN, THERWAS
THIS GUY STANDING THERE
FROM THE RED CROSS.
AT A POINT WHERE I HAD
JUST LOST EVERYTHING,
THE IDEA THAT THERE WAS
SOMEONE THERE...
THAT'S AN AMAZING THING.
♪
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
>>Neil: THE POLICE UPDATING US
ON THE LATEST MUST BEES AND
DETAILS ON THE TRAGIC SHOOTINGS.
A FORMER DETECTIVE SECURITY
EXPERT JOINING US ON THE PHONE,
DETECTIVE, WHAT DO YOU LOOK FOR
AT THIS CRIME SCENE?
IF YOU WENT TO THE SCHOOL, WHAT
WOULD YOU LOOK FOR?
>> YOU ARE LOOKING FOR
EVERYTHING.
YOU WANT TO BE CAREFUL NOT TO
DISTURB THE CRIME SCENE.
THAT WILL BE A CRIME SCENE FOR
HOURS, DAYS, AND MAYBE WEEKS.
YOU ARE LOOKING FOR THE POINT OF
ENTRY.
AMMUNITION.
WEAPONS.
WHETHER THERE WERE NOTES OR
COMMUNICATIONS AT THE SCENE.
THE BARRIER.
PLACEMENT OF THE BODIES.
EVERYTHING YOU CAN FIND ON A
CRIME SEEN.
>>Neil: WHEN WE HAVE A SCENE
WITH SO MANY KILLED AND WE KNOW
THAT THE SHOOTER WAS ARMED FOR
BEAR WITH A NUMBER OF
SEMI-AUTOMATIC WEAPONS AND HE
CAME WITH THE INTENT TO TAKE OUT
A LOT OF PEOPLE, WITH THESE
WEAPONS IT DOES NOT TAKE A LOT
TIME TO DO THAT.
>>Guest: IT DOESN'T.
THE OTHER THING THAT IS CLEAR TO
ME, THIS WAS A WELL-THOUGHT-OUT,
PLANNED ATTACK, AN AMBUSH, BY
THIS KID.
HE HAD A BULLET ROOF VEST ON.
HE HAD THE AMMUNITION.
HE HAD THE ARMOR, EVERYTHING TO
AMBUSH THE POOR INNOCENT
CHILDREN AND THAT TELLS ME HE
HAD PLANNED THIS FOR A
LONG-TERM, NO QUESTION.
>> I ASKED THIS EARLIER AND I
WASN'T TRYING TO BE FLIPPANT WHY
IN SO MANY SCHOOL SHOOTINGS
PARTICULARLY THOSE INVOLVED TO
VERY YOUNG CHILDREN, IN THIS
CASE KINDERGARTENERS, WHY
CHILDREN?
THE MOST INNOCENT AMONG US IN
ESSENCE WHO IS MORE DEFENSELESS
THAN CHILDREN?
I HAVE BEEN IF LAW ENFORCEMENT
INVESTIGATION IF 35 YEARS, PLUS.
THERE IS NO GROUP, CHILDREN JUST
CANNOT DEFEND THEMSELVES.
UNFORTUNATELY, WE HAVE BULLIES,
PEOPLE LIKE THIS KID, WHO GO OUT
HERE AND TAKE FULL ADVANTAGE OF
THAT.
>>Neil: THESE INCIDENTS ARE
GETTING TO BE TOO FREQUENT AND
MANY WILL ARGUE IT IS NOT JUST
IN AMERICA BUT EVERYWHERE.
IS THERE SOMETHING TO THAT?
EITHER WE ARE DESENSITIZED
SOCIETY OR THOSE WHO TAKE IT TO
THIS LEVEL, THIS BIZARRE AND
PROVIDE LENGTH LEVEL, A PATTERN?
>>Guest: THAT IS THE QUESTION.
I DID AN INTERVIEW ON THE
SHOOTING OF THE THEATER, THE
JOKER, THE GIVE WITH THE RED
HAIR, UNFORTUNATELY, THERE IS
SOMEONE, AND PLACE, PLANNING
SOMETHING SIMILAR IF NOT BIGGER
AND BETTER.
UNFORTUNATELY, IT IS A FACT,
SOMEONE IS SITTING SOMEWHERE
RIGHT NEW PLANNING SOMETHING
BETTER AND BIGGER THAN THIS.
>>Neil: AMAZING, BUT,
ACTUALLY, I THINK YOU ARE RIGHT.
DETECTIVE, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WE WILL TRY TO PUT THIS
TOGETHER.
THE LOCAL AUTHORITIES ARE ON THE
SCENE IN CONNECTICUT AND THE
COMMUNITY THAT NOW HAS A
HISTORIC MARK ON IT AFTER THIS.
DRY MOUTH MAY START OFF
AS AN IRRITANT.
IT'LL CAUSE CAVITIES,
BAD BREATH.
PATIENTS WILL TRY AND DEAL
WITH IT BY DRINKING WATER.
WATER WILL WORK
FOR A FEW SECONDS
BUT IF YOU'RE NOT DRINKING IT,
IT'S GOING TO GET DRY AGAIN.
I RECOMMEND BIOTENE.
ALL THE BIOTENE PRODUCTS
LIKE THE ORAL RINSE...THE SPRAYS
HAVE ENZYMES IN THEM.
THE WHOLE FORMULATION
JUST WORKS VERY WELL.
IT LEAVES THE MOUTH
FEELING FRESH.
IF I'M HAPPY WITH THE RESULTS
AND MY PATIENTS ARE HAPPY
WITH THE RESULTS,
I DON'T NEED TO LOOK
ANY FARTHER.
.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with uimited
talk and text.
by HTC for $49.99.
>> Neil: ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE WAITING FOR AUTHORITIES
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, TO
UPDATE US ON WHAT THEY KNOW
AND WHAT THEY CAN POSSIBLY
TELL US.
RICK LEVENTHAL THERE WITH THE
LATEST AS WELL.
RICK?
>> Reporter: NEIL, AS YOU
SAID, WE'RE WAITING FOR UPDATE
FROM THE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE, REGARDING ANY
ADDITIONAL INFORMATION THEY
CAN GIVE US ABOUT THE HORRIFIC
SHOOTING THAT HAPPENED EARLIER
TODAY AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN SANDY
HOOK, WHICH IS IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
CONFIRMED 26 PEOPLE WERE FOUND
DEAD INSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
WERE KILLED IN THAT SHOOTING.
18 CHILDREN DEAD IN THE
SCHOOL.
TWO DIED AT THE HOSPITAL.
SIX ADULTS FOUND DEAD INSIDE
THE SCHOOL, INCLUDING THE
SHOOTER WHO WE ARE TOLD NOW BYWT
SOURCES IS 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM
LANZA.
INITIALLY PEOPLE IDENTIFIED
THE SHOOTER AS 24-YEAR-OLD
RYAN LANZA.
THAT IS ADAM'S BROTHER.
APPARENTLY, ADAM MAY HAVE BEEN
CARRYING RYAN'S I.D. AND
THAT'S WHY THERE WAS CONFUSION
INITIALLY.
WE'RE TOLD THAT THE SHOOTER
WAS ADAM.
HIS BROTHER IS NOW BEING
QUESTIONED BY AUTHORITIES IN
HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY.
WE'RE TOLD ADAM'S MOTHER WAS
KILLED AND A BODY WAS FOUND
INSIDE THE PARENT'S HOME IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
IT'S UNCLEAR WHO THAT BODY IS.
THERE WERE REPORTS THAT THE
FATHER HAD BEEN KILLED BUT WE
CAN'T CONFIRM THAT.
A SWAT TEAM WENT TO THE HOUSE
TO EXECUTE A SEARCH WARRANT.
THEY WENT THROUGH THE DOOR AND
THEN THEY IMMEDIATELY BACKED
OUT BECAUSE OF CONCERNS ABOUT
POSSIBLE BOOBBYTRAP.
THEY SENT IN A ROBOT AND THE
ROBOT IDENTIFIED A BODY INSIDE
THE HOUSE.
CRIME SCENE ONGOING, AND
INVESTIGATION IS ONGOING.
THEY'RE STILL CONTINUING TO
TRY TO RECOVER THE FRED THAT
HOME.
STILL AT THAT SCHOOL, NEIL,
BECAUSE THE BODIES ARE INSIDE.
A LOT HAS TO BE PROCESSED,
PHOTOGRAPHS, DIAGRAMS MADE
BEFORE THEY BEGIN REMOVING
BODIES FROM THE SCHOOL.
>> Neil: IF YOU COULD HANG
ON, WE ARE GETTING WORD FROM
THE WHITE HOUSE THAT THE
PRESIDENT CANCELED THE PLANNED
TRIP WEDNESDAY TO PORTLAND,
MAINE.
NO DOUBT IN LIGHT OF THE
DEVELOPMENTS.
ON WHAT AUTHORITY ARE LOOKING
FOR?
THEY KNOW THE SHOOTER.
THEY KNOW HE IS APPARENTLY
FIRST WENT AFTER HIS MOTHER.
HE KNEW ENOUGH AT THE SCHOOL
TO TARGET PRESUMABLY HER
CLASS.
I SEE IT'S BEGINNING.
>> I WOULD LIKE TO GIVE YOU AN
UPDATE, BRIEFING ON SOME
ADDITIONAL DETAILS.
HOPEFULLY YOU CAN ANSWER SOME
OF THE QUESTIONS THAT YOU MAY
HAVE.
AGAIN, AS I STATED BEFORE.
THIS IS ANGOING CRIMINAL
INVESTIGATION.
WE ARE LIMITED AS TO SOME OF
THE DETAILS WE CAN GIVE OUT TO
YOU FOR OF COURSE REASONS.
FIRST, LET IT BE STATED THAT I
TOLD YOU THE NUMBER OF
DECEASED IN THE BUILDING AT
THE HOSPITAL, SECONDARY CRIME
SCENE.
IT'S THE POLICY AND PROTOCOL
WE HAVE TO ESTABLISH POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATION OF THOSE
VICTIMS.
THAT IS A TIME CONSUMING
PROCESS AND SOMETHING THAT
WILL TAKE TIME.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER ARRIVED
AT THE SCENE.
THIGH WILL EXPEDITE THAT AND
GET THAT DONE AS QUICKLY AS
POSSIBLE.
THE FAMILIES HAVE BEEN
ASSIGNED A TROOPER AND OFFICER
IN COMMUNICATION.
THAT WAS DONE TO ENSURE THE
FAMILIES THEY HAVE CONSTANT
COMMUNICATION WITH THEGOING
INVESTIGATION.
AND THEY WON'T HAVE TO SIT AND
WATCH TELEVISION NEWS OR
ANYTHING ELSE.
THEY WILL BE THE FIRST TO
KNOW.
ANY OF THE PROGRESS MADE AS
THE INVESTIGATION CONTINUES
ON.
HAS I SATED EARLIER, THE
ASSETS UTILIZED WHEN THE CALL
CAME IN, THE NEWTOWN POLICE
DEPARTMENT CALLED FOR HELP,
WITH LOCAL AGENCIES AND THE
OFFICERS AND THE POLICE OFF
DUTY AND ON DUTY TROOPERS TO
RESPOND SO IT CAN IMMEDIATELY
GAIN ASSET TO THAT BEGINNING
TO BEGIN THE SEARCH PROCESS I
ALLUDED TO BEFORE.
WE HAD THE TACTICAL TEAM, WE
HAD TROOPER 1 IN THE AIR.
PROBABLY KEEP YOUR HELICOPTERS
AWAY FRANKLY.
WE HAD EVERY POSSIBLE ASSET
CAME OUT TO THIS SCENE.
THE MINUTE THIS ALARM CAME IN,
THIS CALL CAME IN TO PROTECT
LIFE AND PROPERTY.
THE COMMUNITY HAS BEEN
OUTSTANDING TO SUPPORT THE
EFFORT.
YOU HAVE TAKEN OVER THE PARK.
THEY ARE SHOWING UP AN
OFFERING CONDOLENCES.
DOING EVERYTHING THEY CAN TO
SUPPORT THE VICTIMS, THE
FAMILIES OF THE HORRIFIC
TRAGEDIES.
THE F.B.I. CRISIS MANAGEMENT
TEAM OFFERED TO RESPOND AND IS
GOING TO RESPOND THROUGH
TOMORROW FOR ASSISTING IN
CRISIS MANAGEMENT AND ASSIST
WITH THE FAMILIES AND THE
FAMILIES MEMBERS BUT THE FIRST
RESPONDERS, THE POLICE, FIRE,
EMS.
WORKING WHAT I DESCRIBED AS A
HORRIFIC AND DIFFICULT SCENE.
LOCAL MENTAL HEALTH CRISIS
INTERVENTION TEAM HAD BEEN ON
SCENE.
HAD BEEN HERE ALL OF TODAY
WORKING AND ASSISTING AND HEL
HELPING.
I WANT TO MAKE IT CLEAR, 18
CHILDREN WERE PRONOUNCED DEAD
AT THE SCENE.
TWO CHILDREN WERE TRANSPORTED
TO AREA HOSPITAL OR PRONOUNCED
DEAD AT THE HOSPITAL.
SIX ADULTS PRONOUNCED DEAD AT
THE SCENE.
ALSO THE SHOOTER WAS ALSO
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCENE.
I DON'T HAVE MUCH MORE DETAIL
ABOUT THE SECONDARY SCENE BUT
THERE IS A RELATED SCENE THAT
WE DISCOVERED AS WE CONTINUE
THE CRIMINAL INVESTIGATION;
SPECIFICALLY, INVESTIGATING
THE SHOOTER.
YOU PROBABLY SAW AND SOMEONE
ASKED ABOUT THE BOMB SQUAD.
YES, WE BROUGHT ALL OF OUR
ASSETS IN IN CASE THEY WERE