WEEP.
>> MOURN WITH THOSE WHO AND
CELEBRATE WITH THOSE THAT
CELEBRATE.
>> WE SEE A LOT OF PEOPLE THAT
HAVE OVERCOME.
>> IS THERE ANESS BETWEEN
MENTAL.
AND MAYBE YOU CAN BE ATHEY ARE
THER THE THE SCRIPTURE TAUGS
ABOUT IT SOME OF THE PEOPLE
WHO CHOOSE TO LET THAT SPIRIT
OVER TAKE THEM.
>> I KNOW YOU ARE DOING THAT
AND THEY NEED OUR PRAYERS.
>> SEE YOU TOMORROW NIGHT.
>> NICKY HALLE MADE A
DECISION.
BUT THE NOW OF NEWTOWN WILL
NEVER BE THE SAME AND AN
ENTIRE NATION GRIEVES FOR
FAMILIES IN A SMALL TOWN.
WE'LL TAKE YOU INSIDE OF THE
INVESTIGATION .
>> WE ARE HOLDING BOTH CRIME
SCENES.
LET ANDA A SECONDARY CRIME
SCREEN.
>> THEY ARE WORKING ATHE KNOCK
TO CLEX THE WEAPONS USED THAT
THEY WANT TO KNOW WHERE THOSE
WEAPONS.
EVERY ONE IS EXAMING FOR THE.
NTHEY INCLUDES ANOTHER AND
THIGH ARE INTERVIEWING ARE
FORTUNATELY HAVE TO INCLUDE
THE CHILDREN FROM THE SCHOOL
THAT SURVIVED THE SHOOTING.
THERE ARE MANY, MANY WITNESSES
THAT NEED TO BE INTERVIEWED.
AUTHORITIES ARE SAYING THEY
HAD NO CONTACT WITH ADAM LANZA
AND HE WAS NOT A KNOWN
CRIMINAL IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> THERE WAS NO CONNECTION
SCHOOL OR SCHOOL HERE.
NAND INVESTIGATORS SAID THAT
ADAM LANZA DROVE TO THE SCHOOL
AND HAD FOUR GUNS IN THE COOR
CARRY THREE OF THEM IN THE
SCHOOL.
WE'LL DO EVERYTHING TATAKES TO
UNCOVER THE EVIDENCE AND
CONDUCT INTERVIEWS AND PAINT A
CLEAR PICTURE AS TO HOW AND
WHY THIS TRAGEDY OCCURRED.
>> A LIVE UPDATE AND THE
INVESTIGATION FROM CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE.
FOX NEWS CORRESPONDANT MOLLY
LIME IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> GRETA THERE IS IT NEW
INFORMATION NOT AS MUCH AS IN
THE BEGINNING AND THE DAYS
FOLLOWING, BUT THEY REVEALED
IN THAT HOME, IN THE HOME
WHERE NANCY LANZA'S BODY WAS
FOUND THERE WERE COMPUTERS AND
THEY WERE SMASHED UP AND
LOOKING IN PHONE RECORD CREDIT
CARD RECORDS.
THEY HAD SUCCESS
IN GATHERING THE INFORMATION
ON HOW AND WHY THIS OCCURRED.
INTERESTING INFORMATION IN THE
ATF.
THE MOTHER AND THE SON, NANCY
LANZA.
THEY WERE HER GUNS INVOLVED IN
THE CRIME AND THEY HAD BEEN NO
TO GUNS IN THE PAST.
BUT ADAM LANZA HAD NOT BEG
YOUR PARDON TO A SHOOTING RAIN
IN THE RECENT SIXES.
COMMUPT COLLEGE.
APPARENTLY ADAM LANZA WAS
SPART SHOULD AND ATTENDING
COMMUNITY COLLEGE AND LOOKED
IN TO THE POSSIBILITY OF GOING
TO SCHOOL.
SHE WANTED TO GO WITH HIM TO
MAKE SURE HE GHOT THE
EDUCATION.
>> HERE IN THE COMMUNITY.
THEY ARE TRYING TO GET THE
CHILDREN BACK TO CLASSES,
PARTICULARLY THE ONES ON THE
DAY OF THE CLASS CURE.
NWE ARE STANDING ON THE EDGE
OF THE STREET IN SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY AND LOOKS LIKE WILL
TAKE THEM AND PUT THEM IN A
NEARBY SCHOOL IN MONROE.
>> IT IS CLOSED IN THE LAST
YEAR AND READY TO BE FILLED
AGAIN.
WE WATCHED THE MOVIE VANS
TAKING THE SUPPLIES AND DECKS
AND SET UP A COMMUNITY SCHOOL
IN MON MONROE.
>> IS THERE ANY INFORMATION ON
WHERE THE KILLER WAS ON
THURSDAY THROUGH MONDAY OF
LAST YEAR.
>> I HEAR HE MIGHT HAVE GONE
TO THE RANGE.
WHY WAS HE AT IT COMING UP TO
THE KILLING SPREE.
NTHERE IS INFORMATION ON ADAM
LANS A. AND THERE IS
INFORMATION ABOUT NANCY LADS
LADS.
BUT.S HAVE SAID VERY LITTLE.
THERE ARE SO MANY INUNANSWERED
QUESTIONS.
>> AND OF COURSE.
THERE ARE NO WORD TOZ DESCRIBE
IT MOMENTS AFTER THE NEWTOWN
SCHOOL SLOTTING, PARENTS GO TO
THE LOCAL FIRE HOUSE.
AND JESSICA REKOS PARPTS ARE
CONFRONTED WITH THE WORST NEWS
POSSIBLE.
THEIR DAUGHTER IS NOT COMING.
>> I AM COMING FOR YOU, HONEY.
WHY HAD NOTICE IDEA.
THERE WERE REPORTS OF ONE OR
TWO INJURED.
AFTER 1:15 THEY SAT US DOWN
AND IT SAID IT WAS A TRAGIC
DAY IN NEWTOWN AND 20 CHILDREN
WERE KILLED AND
THEY TOLD ME MY LITTLE GIRL
WAS GONE.
NCONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
JOINS US BY PHONE.
WE SAT AND WATCH THE PAIN .
PARENTS.
AND I AM CURIOUS HOW YOU ARE
DOING.
YOU HAVE BEEN THERE SINCE THE
BEGINNING AND I KNOW THE SITE
HAS BEEN TERRIBLE FOR ALL OF
THE FIRST CONTENERS.
>> IT IS THE WORST CRIME SCENE
MANY OF US HAVE EVER SCENE.
AND OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN FOR
THE FAMILIS AND FRIENDS AND
RELATIVES OF THE POOR CHILDREN
AND PROFESSIONALS IN THAT
BUILDING THAT LOST HER THEIR
LIVES.
>> WHEN YOU SEE THE HEARSES IT
IS HORREBLE.
>> LET ME TURN TO THE KILLER.
DO YOU HAVE ANY INFORMATION ON
WHERE HE WAS.
THE KILLING ON FRIDAY.
BUT ON THURSDAY, WEDNESDAY ASK
MONDAY.
HAVE PEOPLE COME FORWARD
SAYING WE SAW HIM IN SUCH AND
SUCH A PLACE.
>> WHAT IS IMPORTANCE.
WE HAVE IMMENSE AMOUNT OF
INVESTIGATORS.
AND THER LOOKING AT EVERY
FACET OF THE CASEMENT AND ONE
OF THEM TO DETERMINE WHERE HE
WAS ON THE DAY HE WAS BORN
UNTIL THE THEY HE DIED.
>> UNCORVE THE INFORMATION AND
PUT THAT INJURED.
AND EVERYONE HAS A CRYSTAL
ELECTION TICKET AND >> I HAVE
NO DOUBT YOU WILL TURN OVER
EVERY STORM.
AND I KNOW I HEAR YOU THAT YOU
ARE GOING IT.
AND ARE PEOPLE COMING TOWARD
AND TELLING YOU THINGS AND ARE
YOU GETTING INFORMATION.
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN PAPTIVE IN
HELPING TO MOVE THE DAYS
PHOTOCOPY.
IT IS IT A LARGE INVESTIGATION
.
AND WE AND SEE WANT IN THE >>
AND THEY SAID AT A THERE IS NO
CONNECTION.
AND >> THE INFORMATION IS
THERE THERE IS IN PAPT WITH
THE DECOL'VE IN TERMS WHAT
HAVE HE WAS WEARING.
DO YOU UPON WHERE HE PURCHASED
HIS CLOTHES.
I UNDERSTAND THAT HE WAS
WEARING SOME CLOTHES THAT
MIGHT BE A LITTLE BIT.
RESPIRATORY THEY'LL EXAMINE
THE CLOGING AND FIND OUT WHERE
IT WAS PURCHASED AND
EVERYTHING ABOUT THE CLOTHING
AND THE YOUNG MAN WILL IN FACT
BE INVESTIGATED THEY WILL
ANSWER EVERY SINGLE QUESTION
REGARDING HIMMENT >> THERE
WERE WITNESSES THAT SURVIVED
IN THE SCHOOL.
DID THEY DESCRIBE HIM?
DID THEY DESCRIBE WHAT HE WAS
SAYING AND WHETHER HE SAID
ANYTHING AT ALL TO HIM?
>> THE CONVERSATION HAS NOT
BEEN RELEASED YET.
THERE WERE TWO INDIVIDUALS
THAT WILL SURVIVE THAT WERE
WOUNDED SERSELY.
THEY HAD GUN SHOT WUNDS FROM
THE SUSPECT AND THEY WILL BE
CRUCIAL IN THAT INVESTIGATION
AND HELPING US TO MOVE FORWARD
AND GIVING US DEFINITIVE
INFORMATION AND ESTABLISHING A
DEFINITIVE TIME LINE AS TO HOW
AND WHY THIS OCCURRED .
>> THAT IS HELPFUL IN TIMES OF
PLANNING AND WHETHER IT WAS A
SPONTANOUSEST AFTER HOE
BLASTED HIS MOTHER IN THE HEAD
OR NOT.
>> IT WAS A TIP IN TERMS OF
HIS STATE OF MIND.
HE IS A KILLER AND SCHOOL.
AND EVIL.
BUT DID HE SAY ANYTHING AT ALL
THAT PEOPLE HAVE REPORTED TO
YOU?
>> I AM NOT PRIVY TO THE
INTERVIEWS THAT TAKE PLACE
WITH THE DULTS AND THE SCHOOL.
AND CERTAIN LIE THE SURVIVORS.
AND THANK GOODNESS WE ARE UP
TO RESCUE SOME PEOPLE.
IT BREAKS OUR HEARTS THAT WE
DIDN'T GET EVERYBODY OUT OF
THERE.
BUT SYRUPLY THE ADULT STAFFERS
ARE INSTRUMENTAL IN PEACEING
IT BACK TOGETHER.
>> THARCHING YOU.
THE GUNMAN'S WHOLE FAMILY
INSISTS THAT ADAM WAS A GOOD
KID.
>> HE WAS AND HE WAS QUIET.
AND NICE AND GOOD KID.
HE WAS A CHALLENGE TO THE
FAMILY IN THE HOUSE.
AND EVERY FAMILY HAS WOP.
AND I HAVE ONE AND NEVER IN
TROUBLE WITH THE LAW OR
ANYTHING.
NIT IS IT RICH WHO IS A FRIEND
OF THE CHILD'S MOTHER AND HE
HAS A CHOILED WITH AUTISM.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
WHETHER DID UP FIRST MEET
ADAM'S MOTHER.
DOWN IN THE INDUSTRY OF
NEWTOWN THERE IS A TRAUNT BAR
CALLED MY PLACE AND IT IS IT A
LOCAL GATHERING PLACE.
ON SUNDAY NIGHTS THEY DO AN
OPEN MIC.
AND PEOPLE PLAY MUSIC AND I
PLAY GUITAR AND WOULD COME ON
THAT.
SHE WAS WELL LIKED DOUP IN THE
RESTAURANT.
>> DID SHE EVER OPEN UP TO YOU
ABOUT PROBLEMS OIR TROUBLE SHE
WAS HAVING MY DEAL WITHINANCY
WAS I HAVE A SON WITH AUTISM
AND SHE HAD A SON WITH
DISABILITY HE WAS ON THE
AUTISM SPECK RUM BUT HIGH
FUNCTIONING WE WOULD TALK
ABOUT HAD IT COMMESERATE ABOUT
OUR SONS.
SHE WAS PROUD OF BOTH OF HER
SONS DID SHE EVER HINT OR SAY
HE WAS VIOLENT OR ANYTHING
PECULLIAR IN THAT AREA.
>> NO, SHE WAS PROUD OF HER
SON.
HE HAD JUST LEARNED HOW TO
DRIVE THIS SUMMER .
I THOUGHT THAT WAS A BIG
ACCOMPLISHMENT.
MY SON IS ON THE LOWER END OF
THE AUTISM SPECK RUM AND HE
WILL NEVER DRIVE A CAR.
>> WHAT DID YOU THINK AND WHAT
WAS YOUR THOUGHT LISTENING TO
THAT.
>> I WAS IN SHOCK.
NANCY WAS A FRIEND OF MINE.
WHY WOULD HE GO TO AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL DO THISMENT
SHE HAD A HARD TIME BECAUSE HE
WOULDN'T LET HER HUG OR TOUCH.
>> HE WAS SENSITIVE TO TOUCH.
MY SON GOES THE OTHER WAY.
AND HE LIKES DEEP BACK RUBS
AND LIKES TO BE HUGGED.
AND NANCY'S SON DIDN'T WANT TO
BE TOUCH AND IT UPSET NANCY
BECAUSE SHE COULDN'T HUG HER
SON.
>> WAS HE RESPONSIVE TO HER?
>> I KNOW WITH THE GUNS, SHE
TOOK HIM TO THE GUN RANGE AS A
WAY A SINGLE MOM COULD TRY TO
BOND WITH HER SON HE ENJOYED
IT AND WHY SHE DID IT FOR
THANK THANK, -- THANKSGIVING
THEY WENT TO WASHINGTON D.C..
>> IT IS SUCH A BROADSPECTRUM.
AND WAS HE THE KIND OF CHILD
FUNCTIONING.
HEY, I AM GOING TO THE STORE
OR I LOVE YOU.
OR WAS HE COLD AND DEFATCHED
AND UNABLE TO COMMUNE MUCH.
>> FROM MY CONVERSATIONS WITH
NANCY.
I LOVE YOU AND THRATYPE OF
EMOTION WAS NOT WHAT HE WOULD
DO.
LIKE YOU SAID.
HE WAS MORE DETACHED .
ROBBER
>> IF IS CERTAINLY TRAGIC.
ANDY WAS TRYING TO
RICH, THARCHING YOU.
>> AND AS A GUNMAN BURST IN
THE SCHOOL.
ONE NURSE HIDURPED HER DESK.
>> AS I CROUCHED DOWN.
COULD SEE MY DORWAY.
HE WAS IN THE OFFICE AND THEN
TO MY OFFICE.
AND WHEN I HEARD THE DOOR
CLOSE.
AND HE POSSIBLE I COULD SEE
HIM KNOWS NOW.
>> RIGHT IN FRONT.
>> TWEPT FEET AWAY.
NAND FACING HIS BOOTS TO MY
DECK.
NNANCY LANZA VISIT MY PLACE.
ONE OF THIM SHOW BROUGHT THE
BOYS ALONG.
>> WE ARE MORE ABOUT.
IN THE INTERVIEW HOE GAVE ME,
HE DID IT WRITTEN AND NOT ON
CAMERA BECAUSE HE IS GETTING
TIRED.
HE WANTED TO MAKE A COUPLE OFS
D. I SEE A LOT OF BADS AND SHE
WAS NOT ONE OF THEM.
HER SON RYAN ADAM'S OLDER
BROTHER WAS A BUS BOY
HE WAS A QUIET GUY AND SOME
WHAT ACWARD.
>> HE TOLD ME THAT ASBERGER
WAS, -- BUT THE GUN ISSUE.
IT IS GOING TO THE RANGE AND
ADAM WAS FASCINATED WITH GUN
SAFETY AND HAD A LOT OF
INTEREST IN DETAIL TO IT >> I
MARK IF THE BAR OWNERS CAME
TOGETHER AND THEY DID AND
CRIED.
O HE WAS QUIET AND UNUSUAL BUT
NOT VIOLENT.
EVEN THE PEOPLE WHO KNEW HIM
BESTY WERE SHOCKED.
>> THANK YOU.
>> AND STRAIGHT AHEAD INSIDE
OF THE HOME OF ADAM LANZA.
WHAT WAS HIS UPBRINGING LIKE.
HOW THE RECORD IS ON THE
GROUND IN NEW TON.
>> AND A MAJOR ANNOUNCEMENT
FROM SOUTH COLOR COLOR
GOVERNOR HAILY.
HE IS HERE.
E CHANGED UP IN A EXMEXICAN.
AND CHAINED TO THE BED.
HIS PARENTS ARE HERE TO GO ON
THE RECORD.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a
Droid Incredible 4G LTE
by HTC for $49.99.
EXECUTOR OF EFFICIENCY.
YOU CAN SPOT AN AMATEUR
FROM A MILE AWAY...
WHILE GOING SHOELESS
AND METAL-FREE IN SECONDS.
AND YOU...RENT FROM National.
BECAUSE ONLY National
LETS YOU CHOO ANY CAR
IN THE AISLE...AND GO.
YOU CAN EVEN TAKE A FULL-SIZE
OR ABOVE,
AND STILL PAY
THE MID-SIZE PRICE.
NOW THIS...WILL WORK.
[ ale Announcer ]
JUST LIKE YOU, BUSINESS PRO.
JUST LIKE YOU.
GO Naonal.
GO LIKE A PRO.
FOR THEIR ANNUAL FOOTBALL TRIP.
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE.
TRAGICALLY, THEIR DDY
GOT SACKED BY BLACKOUTS.
BUT IT'S OUR TRADITION!
THAT'S ROUGHING
THE CARD HOLDER.
BUT WITH
THE Capital One Venture Card
YOU GET DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE.
[ cheering ]
ANY FLIGHT, ANYTIME.
THE SCOREBOARD DOESN'T LIE.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET? HUT!
I HAVE ME ON MY FANTASY TEAM.
WHAT'S Meet the 5-passenger
Ford C-MAX Hybrid.
When you're carrying
a lot of weight,
C-MAX has a nice little trait,
You see, C-MAX helps
you load your freight,
with its foot-activated
lift gate.
But that's not
all you'll see,
Cause C-MAX also
beats Prius v,
with better MPG.
Say hi to the all-new 47
combined MPG C-MAX Hybrid.
>> THEYY WILL GUARD BOTH
SCENES CRIME SCENES AS
INDICATED THIS MORNING AND
THAL GO ON INDEFINITELY.
REGARDING THE FUN VAL SERVICES
.
THEY ARE BEING PLAN
PUBLICICIZED BY THE FAMILIS
AND THE FUNERAL HOMES.
A COUPLE OF THINGS WE WANT TO
RESTATE.
THEY HAVE A LIASON TREEPER TO
MAINTAIN CONTACT AND BE WITH
THEM.
THEY ARE LENDING ASSISTANCE TO
EACH FUNERAL SERVICE SO IT
GOES UNSCATHED.
WE SEIZED SIGNIFICANT EVIDENCE
IN THE RESIDENCE.
AND TWEE HAVE A PAIN STAKING
IN US .
>> WE DON'T DISCUSS EVIDENCE.
IT IS ITS CONTACT OR DEBAIL
WHAT IT IS.
>> TONIGHT AN INSIDE LOOK AT
THE GUNMAN'S LIFE.
HIS MOTHERAS 22 DRYERED.
HIS FATHER'S EXECUTESIVE AND
HIS MOTHER A HARWORKING MOTHER
WHO LOVES HER TON.
>> IT IS THE HARD IT
UNDERSTAND HOW ANYONE COULD BE
CRUEL.
>> TELL ME ABOUT THE DIVORCE.
>> WE LEARNED THAT PETER AND
NANCY LANS LAPS WERE MARRIED
AND BY ALL ACCOUNTS, IT WAS
NOT ACRIMONOUS.
I TALKED TO BOTH LAWYERS AND
THEY SAID THAT AS DIVORCES GO.
IT SUNDED LIKE THIPPINGS WERE
GOING WELL.
AND THERE WAS NOT A CUSTODY
DISPUTE.
IT WAS SHARED WITH BOTH
PARENTS THOUGH ADAM LIVED WITH
HIS MOM IN NEWTOWN WE LEARNED
ABOUT A FINANCIALS, PETER
LANZA HAD AGREED TO ABOUT
$250,000 OF THE ALIMONEY A
YEAR TO NANCY.
AND SO THAT CAME TO $10,000 A
MONTH SO SHE WAS COMFORTABLE
THERE WAS NO DISPUTE.
>> IT SEEMS AS IF I DO A MOTH
HERE.
ADAM WAS 15 AND CONTINUED TO
LIVE WITH HIS MOTHER AND NEVER
LEFT HOME, IS THAT RIGHT .
THERE WERE PROVISIONS IN THE
DIVORCE ORDER THAT PETER LANZA
WAS TO PAY FOR COLLEGE FOR
ADAM AND HIS BROTHER RYAN AND
ALSO THE FATHER WAS SUPPOSED
TO PAY FOR A CAR FOR ADAM.
AND ADAM WAS JUST STARTING TO
LEARN TO DRIVE A CAR.
AND HIS FATHER WAS FOR THE
PAYMENT OF THAT.
AND NANCY AND ADAM WERE
COMFORTABLE IN THE HOME AND
THEY WERE ABLE TO GEEPKEEP
GOING >> AND THIS IS IT
PROBABLY THE WORST CRIME, THAT
OUR NATION HAS BEEN PICKING ON
I AM CURE BOUSE.
WHAT HE WAS DO DO IT IS THE
DAY BEFORE.
WHERE HE HAD BEEN.
>> IF YOU HAVE COME TOWARD.
>> THERE ARE REPORTERS TROYING
TO FIND ALL OF THAT OUT AND
REALLY GOOD REPORTERS ARE
TRYING TO GET THAT
INFORMATION.
POLICE ARE TIGHT LIPPED AND
NOT LEASING INFORMATION.
THEY EVEN BEFORE.
AND I HAPPENING IT IS A
QUESTION RA'S PEOPLE WANT
ANSWERED.
>> WHENY THERE ON FRIDAY.
HE WAS KNOWN AS A STRANGID
CAN.
I AM NOT EXCUSING MURDERS.
IS THAT THE IMPRESSION YOU ARE
GETTING TO.
THAT THIS IS A BOY AND
NENASING YOUNG MAN WHO WAS
UNUSUALA AT BEST.
>> THAT'S WHAT THEY SAID.
HE WAS WITH DRAW AND NOT OFFER
SOCIAL AND HAD A BACK BLACK
PACK AND BLACK SUITED CASE.
HE DIDN'T ENGAGE.
AND HE DIDN'T AND IT IS SO
HARD TO KNOW HOW SOMEONE CAN
BE PROFOUNDLY EVIL.
THANK YOU.
NTHARCHING YOU.
--.
>> NICKY HALLE HAS MADE A
DECISION.
SHE GOES ON THE RECORD NEXT
HEALTH CONCERNS FORTSING -
FORCING SECRETARY OF STATE
HILLARY CLINTON CANCEL HER
TESTIFYING.
THINK ABOUT THAT.
OBAMA DOLTON NEXT.
Citracal Slow Release.
-- NEXT.
AM
[ Male Announcer ]
THE RHYTHM OF LIFE.
[ whistle blowing ]
WHERE DO YOU HEAR THAT BEAT?
CAMPBELL'S HEALTHY REQUEST SOUP
LETS YOU HEAR IT...
IN YOUR HEART.
[ basketball bouncing ]
HEART HEALTHY.
GREAT TASTE.
MMM...
[ Male Announcer ] SOUNDS GOOD.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
TO THE BEST VACATION
SP(ALL) THE GULF!
[ Male Announcer ] SOUNDS GOOD.
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHICH OF
OUR GREAT STATES FOLKS VISIT.
MISSISSIPPI,
ALABAM
LOUISIANA
OR FLORIDA,
THEY'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
SHAUL, YOUR ALABAMA
HOSPITALITY IS INCREDIBLE.
THANKS, KAREN.
LOVE YOUR MISSISSIPPI OUTDOORS.
I VOTE FOR YOUR
FLORIDA BEACHES, DAWN.
BILL, THIS LOUISIANA
SEAFOOD IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR ON THE GULF,
WE'VE DECIDED TO PUT
ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
NOW IS THE PERFECT TIME TO
VISIT ANYONE OF OUR STATES.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE, GO FISHING
OR JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
WE'VE GOT COASTLINE TO EXPLORE
AND WILDLIFE TO PHOTOGRAPH.
AND THERE'S WORLD CLASS DINING
WITH OUR WORLD FAMOUS SEAFOOD.
SO FOR A GREAT VACATION
THIS YEAR, COME TO THE GULF.
ITS ALL FABULOUS BUT
I GIVE FLORIDA THE EDGE.
RIGHT AFTER MISSISSIPPI.
YOU MEAN ALABAMA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
THIS INVITATION IS
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP
AND ALL OF US WHO
CALL THE GULF HOME.
[ engine revs ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THE MERCEDES-BENZ WINTER EVENT
IS BACK,
WITH THE PERFECT VEHICLE
THAT'S JUST RIGHT FOR YOU,
NO MATTER WHICH LIST YOU'RE ON.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
C250 FOR $349 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAN
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
>> IT NICKY HALLE MAKES AN
ANNOUNCEMENT.
CONGRESSMAN TIM SCOTT.
TIM SCOTT WENT ON THE RECORD .
>> GOVERNOR, NICE TO SEE BOTH
OF YOU.
>> HEY, GRETA.
HOW ARE YOU?
>> I AM WELL.
THIS IS AN EXCITING DAY FOR
SOUTH CARL SCARL AND FIRST
FRECK FRECK SENATOR FROM THE
SOUTH SINCE 1881 AND THE FIRST
FRECK FRECK GOP SEPTEMBEROR IN
THE SENATE SINCE 1979.
I TAKE IT.
EVEN THOUGH IT IS FUN TO BE
FIRST.
IT IS NOT THE REASON YOU CHOSE
CONGRESSMAN SCOTT.
>> WHAT WE WERE LOOKING FOR
SOUTH CARL EXARL AND THE
COUNTRY WAS LEADER AND
CONGRESSMAN SCOTT SHOWED
LEADERSHIP ON THE WAY HE MOVED
UP THROUGH THE HOUSE
LEADERSHIP WITHOUT
COMPROMISING HIS COURAGE.
HE FOUGHT AGAINST RAISING THE
DEBT SOLING.
HE'S DONE ALL OF THAT IN A WAY
TO MAKE SOUTH CAROLINA
PROVIDE.
>> THEY HAVE A POINT OF THIS.
AND WHAT HE EARNED IT FOR THE
PERSON HE IS.
AND AARONED IT FOR THE RESULTS
HE'S PROVEP AND CONTINUE TO
EARN IT FOR THE LEADERSHIP WE
SHOWS.
THE ONLY THING WE WANT ON YOU
TO TAKE OUT OF THE
MINORITIUATION.
ONLY IN THIS COUNTRY AN INDIAN
WOMAN BECOME GOVERNOR AND
FRECK FRECK TO BE FRAN
CONGRESS.
>> WHEN DID THE GOVERNOR CALL
YOU AND WHAT DID SHE SAY TO
YOU?
>> IT WAS LATE YESTERDAY
EVENING WHEN FIRST CALLED ME
AND WE HAD A SIMPLE
CONVERSATION AND IPVITED MOW
TO SIT DOWN AND HAVE A
CONVERSATION.
AND SHE SAID WELL, DO YOU WANT
TO BE A U.S. SEPTEMBEROR.
MY ANSWER WAS YEAH.
>> AND WHAT WILL BE DIFFERENT
BETWEEN THE HOUSE AND THE
SEPTEMBER FOR YOU?
WHAT WERE YOU EXPECTING?
>> I HOPE TO HAVE SIMILARITY
AND FOCUS ON THE ECONOMIC
CLIMATE OF OUR COULD YOU
WANTRY AND NECESSITY OF
DEALING WITH THE AND DEFICIT.
THIS WILL BE MORE OPPORTUNITY
TO GO.
AND NOW THE REPUBLICANS ARE
MOVING IN THE.
AND THRAWILL SHAPE UP MY
EXPERIENCE DRASTICALLY.
>> GOVERNOR, WE WATCHED AND
TIND OUT WHO YOU WOULD PICK.
THERE ARE RULERS AND STUTCH
SUCH.
IT WAS A TOUGH DESIGNATION.
>> IT IS NOT ALWAYS CUT AND
DRIED.
FOR ME THREE OR FIVE EAR 10
YEARS OLD AND WHERE OUR STATE
AND COUNTRY IS GOING.
UP WANT A FIGHT ARE AND MEMBER
THAT HAS CONSESHATIVE
PRINCIPALS AND WILL NOT WAIVER
IN PRESSURE.
WE HAVE GREAT CANDIDATES AND I
AM CONFIDENT ABOUT HIS MOTHER
AND WHAT HE WILL F THIS
EMPLOYWHEN YOU CAME IN THE
HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVE, YOU
ROSE UP FROM POVERTIET TO BE A
MEMBER OF THE UNITED STATES
CONGRESS.
WHY ARE YOU SO SUCCESSFUL AND
WHAT IS IT ABOUT YOU?
>> I THINK IT COMES DOWN TO
THE STRONG FAITH AND THE LORD
ABOVE AND A MOTHER WHO
BELIEVES THAT LOVE HAS TO COME
IN THE END OF THE SWITCH.
AND SHE LOVED ME.
AND A METROPOLITANOR WHO CAME
ALONG IN THE RIGHT TIME AND
TAUGHT ME BASIC BUSINESS
PRINCELES OF CREATING A PROFIT
AND NOT JUST INCOME IT HELPED
ME TO START MY OWN CAREER.
AND I WOULD LOVE TO TELL THEM
HOLD ON AND BEST IS YET TO
COME.
AND BEST WAY TO GET THERE IS
BY GETTING GOVERNMENT OUT OF
THE WAY.
IN AMERICA TODAY WE HAVE A
SPENDING PROBLEM AND NOT
ADDRESSED THAT YET.
I THINK THAT STANDS AS 99 --
IN THE OBSTACLES OF ALL
AMERICANS.
WE ARE DEALING WITH A SLOW
PACE OF OUR ECONOMY.
NGOVERNOR, I DON'T KNOW WHAT
THE RULES ARE ON THE U.S..
IF YOU CAN GET JIM DEMINT AND
PUT YOUR SENIOR IN -- SENATOR
IN THE HEAD OF THE LINE.
YOU GET YOUR GUY IN FIRST AND
SEE IFOR DEMINT WILL LEAVE
SOONER .
>> HE WAS WITH US LONG WITH
SENATOR GRAHAM AND I THINK
SENATOR DIMINT SAID JANUARY 2
HAPPENEDIS THE REZINATION
DATE.
AND WE WILL MOVE FORWARD AND
THE HERITAGE FOUNDATION GOT
LIFTED UP IN A BIG WAY.
>> IT IS ALWAYS EXCITING TO
SEE WHAT IS GOING ON IN
POLITIC AND THINGS ARE EXCITE
NOTHING WASHINGTON.
CONGRESSMAN YOU MUST BE
INTERESTED IN THE FISCAL CLIFF
DEBATE GOING ON WE KEEP
HEARING ABOUT REVENUES AND WE
NEED THE CONVERSATION ABOUT
SPENDING.
THE CHALLENGE IS NO MATTER
WHAT WE DO TO INCREASE TAXES
WILL IT WILL NOT TOUCH IMPACT
THE DEBT.
WE HAVE TO HAVE A SERIOUS
CONVERSATION ABOUT SPENING
REFORM AND BALANCED BUDGET
AMENDMENT AND IF WE START WITH
THAT PART WE WILL MAKE MORE
FROM OUR SPER PECT -
PERSPECTIVE.
THE TRUTH AMERICA ACE BRIGHT
FUTURE.
NNOW, YOU WILL HAVE A WHOLE.
AND HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES
WILL BE KILLED BY SPECIAL
EDUCATION.
SENATOR DEMENT RESIGNS.
AND THE PRIMARY WILL BE HELD.
AND THE RUN OFF WILL BE HELD
TWO WEEKS FROM THAT AND 'WEEKS
WILL BE THE ELECTION .
>> GOVERNOR, IT IS IT ALWAYS
NICE TO SEE YOU.
>> THARCHINGS.
>> COMING UP.
WHAT DOES LINDSAY GRAHAM THINK
ABOUT THE NEWEST SENATE
COLLEAGUES AND WHY DID HE
MENTION US ON THE RECORD?
YOU WILL ARE HAD FROM HIM IN A
MOMENT.
>> AND THERE IS NEWS ABOUT
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON AND HER HEALTH.
SHE HAD TO CANCEL THE HEALTH.
BUT JOHN BOLTON THINKS THERE
IS MORE TO THE STORY, NEXT
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
It's hard to see opportunity
in today's challenging
environment.
Unless you have the right
perspective.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
has the vision
and experience to look beyond
the obvious.
We'll uncover opportunities,
find hidden risk,
and make success a reality.
BNY Mellon Wealth Management
>> IT WAS A POLITICAL LOAVE
FEST AND GOVERNOR NUCKY HALLE
NAMED CONGRESSMAN SCOTT HAS
THE NEXT GOVERNOR.
SENATOR GRAHAMINE GIVING US ON
THE RECORD A SHOUT OUT AND
PRAISING THE CONSERVATIVE
RECORD OF CONGRESSMAN TRAY
GROUTY.
>> TRAY, YOU ARE ON GRETA
ALMOST AS I AM.
THAT IS IMPRESS ITCH.
HE COMES FROM THE CONSERVATIVE
PART OF THE STATE AND THROSE A
PUNCH AND DOES IT IN A WAY
THAT BOTH SIDES OF THE ALL
RESPECT HIM.
HE TALKED ABOUT FAST AND
FURIOUS AND BENGHAZI AND THE
WAY YOU CONDUCT YOURSELF IN
FROPT OF THE NATION.
>> WHAT DO YOU THINK OF OUR
SHOUT OUT.
GO TO GRETA OPINION COM.
BACK IN TWO MINUTES.
(Announcer) When Subaru owners
look in the mirror,
they see more than themselves.
So we celebrate our year-end
with the "share the love" event.
Get a great deal on a new Subaru
and 250 dollars goes to your
choice of five charities.
By the end of this, our fifth
year,
our total can reach almost 25
million dollars.
It's a nice reflection on us
all.
Now through January 2nd.
Get 0% APR financing for 36
months on a 2013 Subaru Forester
and we'll donate 250 dollars to
your choice of 5 charities.
THEY DON'T HELP SINGLE MOMS.
HI!
[ Sarah ] WHAT HAPPENED
TO OUR HOUSE LAST YEAR?
[ Daughters ] IT FLOODED
AND THE WATER FLOODED OUT. YEAH.
[ Sarah ] THE RED CROSS
ARRANGED THE HOTEL FOR US.
THEY GAVE ME THAT BREAK,
THAT LEVERAGE,
TO BE ABLE TO GET IT TOGETHER
AND TAKE CARE OF THEM. YOU KNOW?
I FEEL LIKE WE'VE COME
FULL CIRCLE.
[ Daughter 1 ] LIKE THAT!
[ Daughter 2 ]
THIS IS HOW I'LL DO IT.
[ Sarah ] THERE YOU GO.
>> FOX BUSINESS BRIEF.
STOCKS PUSHING HIGHER ON HOPS
THAT LAW MAKERS ARE GETH
DELOSER TO A DEBT DEAL.
AND MEANWHILE, BUSINESS
ECONOMIST BELIEVE THAT THE
COUNT ROY WILL SEE MODEST
GROWTH WITH STRENGTH FROM THE
REBOUND IN HOUSING.
IT IS LOOKING FOR THE ECONOMY
TO GROW 2.1 PERCENT NEXT YEAR.
AND AMAZON ANNOUNCING A
LICENSING AGREEMENT.
THE MARKET PLACE WILL ADD, TNT
AND GIVING MEMBERS INSTANT
ACESS TO THOSE.
HOBITTED HAULED IN 80.4.
AND DOMESTICALLY WINS.
NOX NOWS NET WORKS GIVING YOU
THE POWER TO TALK.
NPRESIDENT OBAMA CLINTON WILL
BE.
AND TONIGHT SECRETARY CLINTON
IS RECOVERING FROM A FAINTING
SPELL AND A CONCLUSION.
GOOD EVENING.
ANY PROBLEM WITH THE SECRETARY
NOT TESTIFYING?
>> WELL, I THINK SHE WILL HAVE
TO TESTIFY AT SOME POINT.
YOU KNOW EVERY FOREIGN SERVICE
OFFICER IN EVERY FOREIGN
MINISTRY KNOWS THE PHRASE I AM
ABOUT TO USE.
WHEN YOU DON'T WANT TO GO TO A
MEETING OR CONFERENCE OR
EVINT.
YOU HAVE A DIPLOMATIC ILLNESS
AND THIS IS WOB - ON ONE TO
BEAT THE BAN.
IT WAS REVEALED IN A WAY THAT
WAS NOT TRANSPARENT AND I
THINK THERE IS AN OBLIGATION
HERE ESPECIALLY IF SECRETARY
CLINTON DECIDES TO RUN FOR
PRESIDENT.
SHE MAY BE TESTIFYING THIS
WEEK, BUT SHE WILL NOT ESCAPE
IT FOREVER.
>> I DON'T THINK SHE INDICATED
THAT SHE WILL NOT TESTIFY EVER
IT HAS BEEN REPORTED THAT SHE
HAD THE FLU AND A WOMAN WHO
LIVED IN AN AIRPLANE FOR FOUR
YEARS REPORTED THAT SHE WAS
DEHYDRATED AND IF YOU FALL AND
GET A CONCLUSION THAT IS IT A
BRAIN INJURY.
BUT SHE DID SAY THAT SHE IS
GOING TO MAKE AVAILABLE THE
ENTIRE COPY OF THE
INVESTIGATIONS DONE AND
COMPLETED AMBASSADOR PICKERING
AND ADMIRAL MULLEN AND SHE
DEPARTMENT HAVE TO TURN OVER
THE ENTIRE SUMMARY AND THAT IS
IT A POSITIVE STEP FORWARD.
IT IS IT TIME THAT THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE FIPED OUT.
I DON'T LIKE THAT IT IS DONE
CLOSED DOORS ON WEDNESDAY .
THERE IS SOME ASPECTS THAT ARE
CLASSIFIED AND SOME ARE NOT.
I CAN UNDERSTAND WHY THERE IS
TWO HEARINGS.
I TELL YOU THE SECRETARY
STAYED OUT THE PUBLIC LIME
LIGHT.
I THINK SHE WAS WAITING FOR
THE REPORT SO SHE COULD FIND
OUT WHAT IT SAID.
AND NOTHING MORE EMBARRASSING
THAN TO SAY SOMETHING AND THEN
HAVE IT CONTRADICTED AND HAVE
TO CHANGE THE STORY.
SHE HAD A CHANCE TO READ THE
REPORT AND WRITE HER TESTIMONY
AT HER LEISURE AND I THINK
THAT IS NOT TRANSPARENT,
EITHER.
>> TWO QUESTIONS.
DID SHE CHOOSE AMBASSADOR
PICKERING AND ADMIRAL MULEN
AND THAT IS THE FIRST
QUESTION.
ARE THEY GOOD AGGRESSIVE
INVESTIGATORS?
>> IF SHE PICKED TWO THAT WERE
LIGHT WEIGHTS, I WOULD BE SUS.
BUT SHE PICK TWO GOOD ONES.
>> UNDER SECRETARY FOR
MANAGEMENT PATRICK KENNEDY
PICKED THEM.
I WOULD LIKE TO SO THE REPORT
BEFORE JUDGING THE
PERSONALITYINGS.
TWO EVENTS SECRETARY CLINTON
MANAGE TOD AVOID BEING IN
PUBLIC.
TWO CRITICAL POINTS SHE WAS
UNAVAILABLE.
FIRST, THE FAMOUS SUNDAY TALK
SHOWS IN FIVE DAYS AFTER THE
ATTACK.
AND AMBASSADOR RICE WROTE IN
THE WASHINGTON POST LAST WEEK,
THAT SECRETARY CLINTON WAS
UNAVAILABLE BECAUSE SHE HAD A
GRUELING WEEK.
AND THE LOSS OF HER FOUR
COLLEAGUES WOULD BE GRUELING.
BUT PRESIDENTS CAN HAVE
GRUELING WEEKS.
PRESIDENT ROOSE VET APPEARED
ON A MEMBER OF CONGRESS AND HE
HAD A GRUELING DAY.
AND IT DEPARTMENTIN
IBCAPACITATE HIM AND NOW
SENATOR CLINTON CAN'T TESTIFY
THIS WEEK.
TWO POINTS DON'T MAKE A
PATTERN BUT MAKE A LINE.
>> I DON'T UNDERSTAND WHY THE
REPUBLICANS HAVEN'T PUT FEET
TO THE FIRE AND ISSUED
SUBPEONAS FOR EVERYONE.
AND I WISH THEY WOULD PUT THE
FEET TO THE FIRE AND I WOULD
HAVE SUBPEONED ERCH. THAT IS
JUST ME.
>> SOUNDS GOOD TO ME.
>> STRAIGHT AHEAD, AN AMERICAN
MARINE CHAINED TO A BED
ARRESTED FOR CARRYING A
REGISTERED GUN.
HIS PARENTS SHOWED THE PHOTOOF
HIM CHAINED TO THE BED, ON THE
RECORD, NEXT.
>>.
>>
THIS DECEMBER, REMEMBER
--
>>
♪
...COULD END
WITH ADDING A CLOSE FRIEND.
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
>> GRETA: A FOMPL FORMER U.S.
MARINE IS CHAINED TO A BED
ARRESTED FOR BRINGING A GUN
INTO THE COUNTRY THAT IS
PROBABLY LEGAL.
THE MARINE'S PARENTS HAVE BEEN
WORKING TO FREE THEIR SON.
TONIGHT, JOHN AND LIDAR HERE
TO GO ON THE RECORD.
GOOD EVENING.
>> GOOD EVENING.
>> HI, HOW ARE YOU?
>> VERY WELL.
I SAW THIS PICTURE OF YOUR SON
CHAINED TO HIS BED.
IS THERE ANY DOUBT IN YOUR
MIND IT'S AUTHENTIC?
>> NO.
>> AND CALL THE GOVERNMENT
HELPING YOU?
>> OUR LAWMAKERS ARE LOBBYING
FOR HELP.
I DON'T KNOW THEY CAN MAKE IT
HAPPEN.
I THINK ADMINISTRATION IS
GOING TO HAVE TO GET INVOLVED
IF GOITSING TO CHANGE THE
SITUATION.
>> I AM APPALLED THEY COULD
HAVE.
LOOK AND LOOK AT WHAT LIBYA
DID.
AND OUT OF A SCOTTISH JAIL TO
BRING HIM BACK AND ANYTHING
LIKE THAT.
AND THE GOVERNMENT ALL THE
TIME ARE REAL -- WHEELING AND
DEALING.
WE'VE GIVEN $1.9 BILLION TO
MEXICO SO OUR GOVERNMENT CAN
DO SOMETHING IF THEY WANT TO.
>> AND WITH THE NEW
ADMINISTRATION IN MEXICO YOU'D
THINK THAT IT WOULD JUST BE A
MATTER OF A CONVERSATION.
>> GRETA: WHAT DID THEY SAY?
IS ANYONE FROM THE STATE
DEPARTMENT CONTACTED YOU?
>> YOU KNOW, WE'VE HAD LETTER
FRTZ STATE DEPARTMENT, JUST
SAYING THAT THEY'RE CONSTANTLY
IN TOUCH WITH THE CONSULATE TO
ENSURE HIS PERSONAL SAFETY TO
ENSURE HE'S GETTING FOOD.
FOR A WHILE HE WASN'T GETTING
FOOD.
THEY'RE CHECKING ON HIM TO BE
SURE HE'S GETTING FED.
TO TALK TO HIM, YOU KNOW?
FIND OUT IF THERE HAD BEEN
HARASSING THINGS GOING ON.
THAT KIND OF THING.
BUT THEY WILL NOT HELP YOU IN
ANY WAY IN YOUR LEGAL CASE.
>> GRETA: I JUST FIND THAT, I
MEAN, IT'S SO -- WRONG.
I MEAN, OUR STATE DEPARTMENT
CAN HELP YOU.
THEY CAN DO THAT.
GOVERNMENTS DO DO THAT.
I MEAN, I DON'T KNOW WLA TO
SAY TO YOU.
ARE YOU OUTRAGED YOU'RE NOT
GETTING HELP FROM THE STATE
DEPARTMENT?
>> WE'RE FRUSTRATED.
YOU KNOW?
WE KNOW THAT BEHIND THE SCENES
OUR ATTORNEY IS TALKING TO THE
MEXICAN ATTORNEY GENERAL, AND
WE KNOW THAT CONGRESS WOMAN
LAIGT ONHAS BEEN IN TOUCH WITH
MEXICAN OFFICIALS.
WE'RE VERY FRUSTRATED YES.
>> GRETA: THAT IS FINE,
THEY'RE TALKING BUT THEY'RE
NOT GETTING ANYWHERE.
TIME IS UP.
YOUR SON HAS BEEN THERE SINCE
AUGUST.
THERE IS SOME DISCUSSION
WHETHER THEY MEASURED THE
BARREL WRONG ON THE GUN,
WHETHER OR NOT IT'S ILLEGAL.
BUT I -- GOVERNMENTS CAN DO
THIS.
WE'VE GOT A LOT OF INFLUENCE
IN MEXICO.
I HOPE THE STATE DEPARTMENT
HELPS YOU, SIR.
>> THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> GRETA: COMING UP RRX SEVEN
ADULTS AND 20 CHILDREN BUNNED
DOWN.
THE PRESIDENT'S TRIBUTE TO THE
CHILDREN, THAT IS NEXT.
NEW PRILOSEC OTC WILDBERRY
IS THE SAME FREQUENT HEARTBURN
TREATMENT AS PLOSEC OTC.
NOW WITH A FANCY COATING
THAT GIVES YOU A BURST
OF WILDBERRY FLAVOR.
NOW WHY MAKE A FLAVORED
HEARTBURN PILL?
BECAUSE THIS IS AMERICA.
AND WE DON'T JUST
MAKE THINGS YOU WANT,
WE MAKE THINGS YOU
DIDN'T EVEN KNOW YOU WANTED.
LIKE A SPOON FORK.
SPRAY CHEESE.
AND JEANS MADE
OUT OF SWEATPANTS.
SO GRAB YOURSELF SOME
NEW PRILOSEC OTC WILDBERRY.
[ Male Announcer
ONE PILL EACH MORNING.
2HOURS. ZERO HEARTBURN.
SATISFAION GUARANTEED
OR YOUR MONEY BACK.
TRY RUNNING FOUR.NING
A RESTAURANT IS HARD,
FORTUNATELY WE'VE GOT INK.
IT GIVES US 5X THE REWARDS
ON OUR INTERNET, PHONE
CHARGES AND CABLE,
PLUS AT OFFICE SUPPLY STORES.
REWARDS WE PUT RIGHT
BACK INTO OUR BUSINESS.
THIS IS THE ONLY THING
WE'VE EVER WANTED TO DO
AND INK HELPS US DO IT.
MAKE YOUR MARK
WITH INK FROM CHASE.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a
Droid Incredible 4G LTE
by HTC for $49.99.
>> GRETA: LAST NIGHT THE
PRESIDENT REMEMBERED VICTIMS
ONE BY ONE IN FRONT OF THE
NEWTOWN AUDITORIUM FILLED WITH
PARENTS CAN CHILDREN.
TONIGHT REMEMBERING YOUNG
CHILDREN CRUELLY GUNNED DOWN
IN FRIDAY'S SCHOOL TRAGEDY.
>> CHARLOTTE, DANIEL, OLIVIA,
JOSEPHINE, ANA, DYLAN, MAD
LYNN, KAJERIN, CHASE, JESSE,
JAMES, GRACE, EMILY, JACK