♪
>>  WELL, THE HOME OF THE
SUSPECT IN THIS CASE, IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT IS ALSO A
CRIME SCENE AT THIS HOUR, IT'S
THERE WHERE POLICE SAY THE
SUSPECT ALSO GUNNED DOWN HIS
MOTHER BEFORE HE DROVE TO THE
SCHOOL TO CARRY OUT A
MASSACRE.
ANNA KOOIMAN LIVE FROM OUR NEW
YORK CITY NEWS ROOM WITH THAT
PART OF THE STORY.
>> CONNECTICUT AUTHORITIES
SAYING THERE'S NO INDICATION
AFTER MOTIVE AT THE MOMENT AND
NO NOTE HAS BEEN FOUND OF.
IT'S BEEN REPORTED THE LAST
FEW YEARS HAVE BEEN ROCKY FOR
THE ALLEGED THE SHOOTER
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA AND
2006 HIS OLDER BROTHER,
24-YEAR-OLD RYAN LANZA LEFT
AND WENT OFF TO COLLEGE AND
LEFT ADAM AT HOME WITH THE THE
PARENTS WHOSE MARRIAGE WAS
COMING APART.
A DIVORCE IN 2009.
CONFUSION OVER THE SHOOTER MAY
HAVE BEEN BECAUSE OF ADAM
CARRYING RYAN'S I.D.
AND HE SAID IT WASN'T ME, I
WAS AT WORK.
COMPUTER AND PHONE RECORDS ARE
SEARCHED AND FBI AND HOBOKEN
POLICE WERE INVESTIGATING AND
RUNNING THROUGH THE HALLWAYS.
>> IN THE BACK OF YOUR HEAD
WHAT COULD HAVE POSSIBLY
HAPPENED?
THERE'S HUNDREDS AND HUNDREDS
OF THINGS, AND YOU KNOW,
YOU'RE JUST SHOOK, YOU CAN'T
HELP IT.
YOU KNOW, HUG YOUR OWN
CHILDREN YOU KNOW, A LITTLE, A
LITTLE MORE AT NIGHT WHEN YOU
PICK THEM UP.
IT'S AN AWFUL STORY.
>> THE FBI TELLING BOTH
BROTHER AND FATHER ARE OF
CLEARED.
AND PETER IS REMARRIED AND THE
HOME, IT'S UNCLEAR IF THEY'RE
INSIDE.
AND NANCY THE MOTHER HAS NO
CONNECTION WITH THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY, BUT ADAM COULD
HAVE GONE THERE AT ONE POINT.
AND FATHER HAS BEEN ESTRANGED
FROM DAD FROM HIM FOR YEARS
AND HE HAD ASPERGER'S, HE WAS
A LONER AND SOCIALLY AWKWARD.
>> Jamie: APPRECIATE THE FACTS
ON THAT, BUT WE'RE NOT GOING
TO SPECULATE OR SAY THAT ANY
OF THOSE DESCRIPTIONS OF THE
SUSPECT DID IN ANY WAY COULD
BE A MOTIVE OR A CAUSE FOR HIM
TO ACT IN THIS WAY.
>> RIGHT.
>> THANKS, ANNA, A GREAT PART
OF THAT STORY, THANKS.
>> Rick: WHILE THE ENTIRE
COUNTRY COMES TO GRIPTS WITH
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT WE'RE
GETTING THE VIDEO INTO THE
NEWS ROOM, PEOPLE FROM NEWTOWN
AND PROBABLY SOME SURROUNDING
AREAS AS WELL WHO ARE
GATHERING OUTSIDE OF THE ST.
ROSE OF LIMA CATHOLIC CHURCH
WHERE PEOPLE ARE LEAVING
FLOWERS, STUFFED ANIMALS,
NOTES TO ALL THE VICTIMS.
ONE PERSON LEFT A NOTE ON A
CANDLE THAT READS, MAY YOU
REST IN PEACE, GONE TOO SOON,
LITTLE ANGELS OF GOD.
LET'S TALK ABOUT THE ROLE THAT
FAITH PLAYS IN COPING WITH
TERRIBLE TRAGEDY LIKE THIS.
JOINING US NOW IS RABBI EVAN
MOVE FIT OF CONGREGATION
SOLAY.
AND FATHER JONATHAN MORRIS.
I CAN'T TELL YOU HOW GRATEFUL
WE ARE ON YOU COMING ON INFORM
THIS TERRIBLE TIMES.
AND FATHER, A LOT OF PEOPLE
WHO MIGHT NOT PRAY ARE PRAYING
NOW NO DOUBT.
>> IT'S A NATURAL REACTION TO
TRAGEDY AND AT THE SAME TIME
PEOPLE ARE SAYING OF COURSE,
HOW COULD A GOOD AND POWERFUL
GOD ALLOW THIS TO HAPPEN.
AND GOD WOULD INTERVENE
BECAUSE HE'S ALL POWERFUL.
WHAT HELPS ME IS TO LOOK AT IT
FROM A DIFFERENT PERSPECTIVE
AND THAT IS, WHY WOULD GOD
ALLOW FREE WILL?
AND I BELIEVE IT'S A VERY
SIMPLE EXPLANATION.
BECAUSE WITH THAT FREE WILL WE
HAVE AN OPPORTUNITY TO LOVE
AND MOST PEOPLE DO IT PRETTY
WELL AND SOME PEOPLE
UNFORTUNATELY TAKE THAT FREE
WILL AND TURN IT AGAINST THE
VERY PEOPLE THAT GOD HAS LOVED
SO DEEPLY, TO CREATE US AND TO
GIVE US THIS GREAT GIFT.
>> Rick: RABBI, AS A PARENT
YOURSELF OF YOUNG CHILDREN AND
I AM, TOO, I'M STILL IN A
STATE OF SHOCK AND I IMAGINE
PEOPLE ALL OVER THE COUNTRY
ARE.
AND HOW DO YOU GET PAST THE
SHOCK AND HOW DO YOU BEGIN THE
SEARCH FOR COMFORT IN A TIME
LIKE THIS?
>> IT'S INCREDIBLY HARD AND
I'M IN THAT STATE OF SHOCK AS
WELL.
AND I THINK WHAT FATHER
JONATHAN JUST SAID IS VERY
PROFOUND AND IN JEWISH
TRADITION, WE HAVE AN IDEA
THAT AT TIMES OF TRAGEDY, GOD
CRIES ALONGSIDE US.
AND WE HAVE TO SIMPLY DRAW
FROM OUR RESERVOIR OF FAITH.
AND BE HONEST THAT THE ANSWERS
WE DON'T KNOW, BUT ALSO TO
BRING AS MUCH COMFORT TO THE
KIDS AND SAY WE DO EVERYTHING
WE CAN TO KEEP YOU SAFE AND WE
DO EVERYTHING WE CAN TO MAKE
SURE THAT SOMETHING LIKE THIS
DOESN'T HAPPEN, BUT THERE'S
TRAGEDY IN THE WORLD.
AND WE GIVE THEM HOPE WITH OUR
PRESENCE, WITH OUR PRAYERS.
>> FATHER JONATHAN, WHY DO WE
KEEP SEEING, AS THE PRESIDENT
SAID YESTERDAY, TOO MANY
TIMES, THESE KINDS OF THINGS
HAPPENING, WHY?
>> WELL, FIRST OF ALL, I JUST
LOVE WHAT THE RABBI SAID THAT
GOD CRIES ALONG WITH US AND
WHEN WE SEE THIS HAPPENING
OFTEN AS YOU MENTION RICK, WE
ASKED THE QUESTION WHY.
AND THAT ANSWER, THAT QUESTION
IS PROFOUND BECAUSE WE SEE IT
HAPPENING IN OUR SOCIETY, THAT
SEEMS TO BE SO AFFLUENT, SO
GOOD, SO HUMAN, SO DEVELOPED.
AND I THINK IT GOES BACK ONCE
AGAIN TO OUR ABILITY TO CHOOSE
TO EITHER LOVE OR TO BE
SELFISH AND WHEN GOD CREATED
US, HE ENTERED INTO A COVENANT
WITH US, THAT SAYS I LOVE YOU
NOT WITH OBJECTS, BUT A BEING
AND SPARKED, LOVE IS A
PRECIOUS GIFT TO BE USED
HOWEVER YOU WISH BECAUSE I
WANT TO HAVE A RELATIONSHIP
WITH YOU, WE COULD GET INTO
WHETHER OR NOT THERE ARE
CULTURAL DEVELOPMENTS THAT ARE
MAKING US MORE--
THIS HAPPEN MORE OFTEN THAN
BEFORE, WHETHER IT'S GUNS,
WHETHER THAT THIS, WHETHER
IT'S THAT.
NOW IS NOT THE TIME.
NOW IS THE TIME TO HUG, NOW IS
THE TIME TO BE CLOSE AND NOW
IS THE TIME TO MAKE A PROMISE
I WILL NEVER USE MY FREE WILL
TO HURT ANOTHER PERSON.
>> Rick: HERE WE ARE, TONIGHT
IS THE LAST NIGHT OF HANUKKAH,
RABBI, AS OUR FAMILY LIT THE
MENORAH, I COULDN'T HELP, BUT
THINK WE WERE LIGHTING CANDLES
FOR THE VICTIMS IN
CONNECTICUT.
AS CHRISTMAS TIME IS NEAR AS
WELL, IS THERE A PRAYER TO
SHE
SHARE WITH US AND THE AUDIENCE
THAT MIGHT HELP US NOW?
>> WELL, THERE IS A PRAYER OF
HOPE.
NOW, ONE OF THE PRAYERS WE SAY
IN HANUKKAH IS WE THANK GOD
FOR THE MIRACLES THAT WERE
DONE FOR GENERATIONS PAST AND
FOR THE MIRACLE THAT GOD DOES
FOR US TODAY.
AND AS I HEARD YOUR LAST STO
ABOUT THESE HEROIC TEACHERS
AND WHAT THEY DID, TO ME,
THEY'RE MODERN MACCABEES IN A
WAY AND THEY PERFORM MIRACLES,
ONE OF THE LESSONS OF
HANUKKAH, WE LIGHT EACH
CANDLES EACH NIGHT AND TONIGHT
IS THE LAST NIGHT SO THAT
GIVES US HOPE.
THERE ARE PEOPLE OUT HERE WHO
HEAL, TO COMFORT, WHO FIGHT
FOR LIFE AND I THINK THOSE ARE
THE PEOPLE THAT MAKE THE
CHOICES FOR GOOD.
SO IN EFFECT, WE THANK GOD FOR
THE MIRACLES EVER THE PEOPLE
THAT WE HAVE TODAY AND THE
COMFORT THAT WE CAN BRING TO
ONE ANOTHER.
>> Rick: THANK YOU FOR THAT,
FATHER JONATHAN, LAST WORD, A
COUPLE OF SECONDS LEFT.
YOUR THOUGHTS AS WE COME UP ON
THE CHRISTMAS HOLIDAY?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, PEOPLE WHO
ARE WATCHING THIS ALL OVER
THIS COUNTRY ARE ASKING
THEMSELVES, WHAT CAN I DO?
AND WE CAN ALL DO SOMETHING.
IN THIS AGE OF MASS MEDIA AND
SOCIAL MEDIA, WE CAN ALL REACH
OUT TO THE PEOPLE WE LOVE
WHETHER THEY'RE NEXT TO US OR
FAR AWAY AND SAY "I LOVE YOU."
AND THAT'S THE GREAT GIFT THAT
JESUS BIRTH GAVE US AND AS
CHRISTIANS THAT GOD CAN LOVE
US AND WE CAN LOVE IN RETURN.
>> Rick: THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> AMEN.
>> Rick: FATHER JONATHAN
MORRIS AND RABBI.
>> Jamie: AFTER THE HORRIFIC
SHOOTINGS IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT MANY OF THE MANY
QUESTIONS THAT SEEM TO COME
OUT OF A TRAGEDY LIKE THIS,
WHAT DO YOU SAY TO YOUR OWN
CHILDREN EVEN IF THEY DIDN'T
GO TO THE SCHOOL.
WE HAVE IMPORTANT ANSWERS FOR
ALL PARENTS.
THAT'S NEXT.
♪
D I TOOK NYQUIL,
BUT I'M STILL "STUBBED" UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
S
F YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT DOESN'T HAVE A DECONGESTANT.
NO WAY.
[ Male Announcer ] SORRY.
Alka-Seltzer Plus FIGHTS
YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A FAST ACTING
DECONGESTANT
TO RELIEVE YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
[ sighs ] THANKS!
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus.
♪ OH
WHAT A RELIEF IT IS! ♪
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
AND SAVE $1
VISIT Alka-Seltzer ON FACEBOOK.
GIVES YOU 1% CASH BACK
ON ALL PURCHASES,
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS.
AND EVERYONE...BUT HER
LIKES 50% MORE CASH.
BUT I'M UPPING MY GAME.
DO YOU WANT A CANDY CANE?
YES!
DO YOU WANT THE PUPPY?
DO YOU WANT A TRICYCLE?
YES!
DO YOU WANT
50 PERCENT MORE CASH?
NO!
♪
FESTIVE.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE Capital One
Cash Rewards Card
GIVES YOU
1% CASH BACK
ON EVERY
PURCHASE
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS
ON THE CASH YOU EARN.
IT'S THE CARD FOR PEOPLE
WHO LIKE MORE CASH.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
>>  AS WE'RE FOLLOWING THE NEW
DEVELOPMENTS THIS HOUR ON THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTING
TRAGEDY THAT EVERYBODY IS JUST
TRYING TO COME TO GRIPS ABOUT,
YOU KNOW, AS WE REPORT AT THE
TOP OF THIS HOUR, POLICE SAY
THEY'RE NOW SAYING THEY'VE
BEEN UNABLE TO ESTABLISH ANY
CONNECTION BETWEEN ADAM
LANZA'S MOTHER AND THE SCHOOL
WHERE THIS TRAGEDY TOOK PLACE,
DESPITE THE EARLIER REPORTS
THAT SHE MAY HAVE WORKED THERE
EVEN AS A SUBSTITUTE TEACHER.
NOW AT THE SAME TIME MANY OF
PARENTS ARE TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT THE BEST WAY TO REASSURE
THEIR CHILDREN AFTER LEARNING
ABOUT AN EVENT LIKE THIS.
DANIEL IS AN ADOLESCENT AND
CHILD PSYCHOLOGIST AND WE ARE
GRATEFUL THAT YOU'RE JOINING
US TODAY, THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU, JAMIE, GLAD TO
BE HERE.
>> Jamie: AND I WISH IT WAS
UNDER DIFFERENT CIRCUMSTANCES.
WE HAVE ONE MOTHER WHOSE
DAUGHTER OLIVIA WAS IN THE
EIGHT-YEAR-OLD AND KNOWING
THAT MORE QUESTIONS COME UP
WHEN NEW FACTS COME OUT.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO HAVE A CHILD
IN THE SCHOOL THOUGH, RICK AND
I ARE BOTH PARENTS AND OUR
CHILDREN ASK QUESTIONS WHAT
HAPPENED.
HOW MUCH DO YOU SAY, DO YOU
TELL THE TRUTH?
>> WELL, I THINK IT DEPENDS ON
THE AGE OF THE CHILD.
I THINK IT HAS TO BE DONE IN A
DEVELOPMENTALLY APPROPRIATE
WAY AND IT'S VERY HARD TO MAKE
SENSE OF SOMETHING THAT'S SO
SENSELESS, BUT I THINK
LIMITING YOUR CHILD'S EXPOSURE
TO THE EVENTS WHICH ARE ON THE
MEDIA HOW 24/7 AND TRYING TO
TALK TO THEM IN A VERY DOWN TO
EARTH WAY, BUT I THINK SPARING
SOME OF THE DETAILS IS THE WAY
TO GO.
FOR EXAMPLE, YOUNG CHILDREN, I
THINK YOU NEED TO REINSTILL A
SENSE OF SECURITY IN THEM AND
MAKE THEM FEEL LIKE THEY'RE
GOING TO BE SAFE AND THIS IS
SOMETHING A RARE EVENT AND
DOESN'T HAPPEN ALL THE TIME
AND THAT, YOU KNOW, IN ALL
LIKELIHOOD THEY'LL BE SAFE.
>> THAT'S WHAT THE MOM
ACTUALLY HAD TOLD HER
DAUGHTER, THIS ISN'T THE WAY
IT'S SUPPOSED TO GO AND SHE
HOPES HER DAUGHTER WILL GO
BACK TO SCHOOL SOON TO GET
BACK INTO HER ROUTINE.
I HEARD SOMETHING INTERESTING
TODAY AND I WANT TO ASK YOU
ABOUT IT, THAT CHILDREN DON'T
ACTUALLY KNOW, WHEN THEY SEE
VIDEO, LET'S SAY THAT THE
STILL PICTURES OF THE CHILDREN
BEING LED OUT OF THE SCHOOL,
WHEN THEY SEE THIS OVER AND
OVER, THEY DON'T HAVE A WAY,
YOUNG CHILDREN, OF KNOWING
THAT IT'S A REPEAT OF VIDEO OR
THIS PHOTOGRAPH.
THEY THINK IT MAY BE HAPPENING
AGAIN AND AGAIN.
DO YOU FEEL IT'S TRUE?
>> WELL, I THINK YOU COULD
HAVE TO EXPLAIN IT TO THEM.
CERTAINLY THEY MAY SEE IT THAT
WAY, KIDS, ESPECIALLY YOUNG
CHILDREN ARE NOT GOOD AT
VERBALLIZING THEIR EMOTIONS
AND THEY TEND TO ACT OUT.
I THINK AS A PARENT YOU REALLY
HAVE TO TRY TO HAVE AN OPEN
LINE OF COMMUNICATION AND
SPEAK TO THEM ABOUT THIS IN A
WAY THAT THEY CAN UNDERSTAND
AND APPRECIATE.
>> Jamie: IF WE WANT TO BE
PROACTIVE WITH OUR CHILDREN
AND PREPARE THEM THAT THESE
THINGS DO HAPPEN IN PLACES YOU
WOULDN'T EXPECT.
WHAT ADVICE CAN WE GIVE OUR
CHILDREN ON HOW TO TRY TO
PROTECT THEMSELVES?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, WE NEED TO
FOCUS ON THE MENTAL HEALTH OF
OUR KIDS, AND WE NEED TO RELY
LESS ON METAL DETECTORS AND
MORE ON MENTAL HEALTH
DETECTORS AND I THINK THIS
COULD HAVE BEEN A WAY TO AVOID
THE TRAGEDY.
I THINK IF WE CAN LEARN
ANYTHING FROM THE TRAGEDY,
IT'S THAT WE HAVE TO BE
PROACTIVE AND WHEN WE SEE
SOMETHING HAPPENING IN OUR
CHILDREN, WE HAVE TO NIP IT IN
THE BUD BEFORE IT BECOMES
SOMETHING HORRIFIC, SUCH AS
THIS EVENT.
>> WE CAN HOPE SO, CORRECT ME
IF YOU'LL WRONG, BUT THE FACT
THAT THE SUSPECT MAY HAVE BEEN
ON THE ASPERGER'S SPECTRUM.
I DON'T WANT TO JUMP TO
CONCLUSIONS AND I DON'T WANT
TO USE IT AS AN EXCUSE FOR BAD
AND HORRIFIC BEHAVIOR.
MANY PEOPLE WHO MAY BE LONERS
OR MAY BE ON THE SPECTRUM HAVE
VERY FULFILLING AND PRODUCTIVE
LIVES AND NEVER GET INTO
TROUBLE, CORRECT?
>> WELL, THAT'S CORRECT.
ASPERGER'S DISORDER IS
CHARACTERIZED BY PARTIALLY A
LACK OF EMPATHY FOR OTHERS AND
THAT MAY HAVE PLAYED A ROLE,
BUT THERE ARE VERY HIGH
FUNCTIONING ASPERGER'S PEOPLE
THAT LEAD VERY PRODUCTIVE
LIVES, AS YOU'VE SAID, AND
IT'S ON THE AUTISTIC SPECTRUM
SO A LOT OF TIMES THESE PEOPLE
HAVE DIFFICULTY RELATING TO
OTHER PEOPLE AND FEELING
EMPATHY, BUT CERTAINLY IT
CAN'T BE GENERALIZED TO ALL
PEOPLE WITH ASPERGER'S
DISORDERS.
>> Jamie: QUICKLY BEFORE WE
GO, WILL THIS COMMUNITY
RECOVER?
>> I THINK IT WILL.
I'VE SEEN AN ENORMOUS
OUTPOURING OF SUPPORT FROM THE
COUNTRY AND I ACTUALLY KNOW
THIS TOWN PERSONALLY FROM MY
OWN PAST.
I THINK IT'S A TIGHT KNIT
COMMUNITY AND SUPPORT EACH
OTHER AND IN THE END EVERYONE
IS GOING TO BE FINE, BUT
ULTIMATELY THE HEALING WILL
TAKE A WHILE.
>> Jamie: ABSOLUTELY.
WE HOPE FOR THAT.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Jamie: RICK.
>> Rick: SCENES OF HORROR.
WE'LL SPEAK WITH ONE PARENT
WHOSE SON WAS IN THE CLASSROOM
WHEN THE GUNMAN BURST IN AND
STARTED FIRING.
ER'S CRABFEST
ENDS SOON.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OURENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
YOU'LL ALSO CARE ABOUT
OUR NEW OFFER.
YOU GET ACCESS TO NURSES WHO
CAN HELP WITH YOUR QUESONS.
AND YOUR LOVED ONE CAN GE
EXELON PATCH FREE FOR 30 DAYS.
IF THE DOCTOR FEELS
IT'S RIGHT FOR THEM.
IT CANNOCHANGE
HOW THE DIASE PROGRESSES.
HOSPITALIZATION
AND RARELY ATH
HAVE BEEN REPORTED IN PATIENTS
WHO WORE MORE THAN ONE PATCH
AT A TIME.
THE MOST COMMON SIDE EFFECTS
OF EXELON PATCH
ARE NAUSEA, VOMITING,
AND DIARRHEA.
THE LIKELIHOOD AND SEVERITY
OF THESE SIDE EFFECTS
MAY INCREASE
AS THE DOSE INCREASES.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
LOSS OF APPETITE OR WEIGHT.
PATIENTS WHO WEIGH
LESS THAN 110 POUNDS
MAY EXPERIENCE
MORE SIDE EFFECTS.
PEOPLE AT RISK
FOR STOMACH ULCERS
WHO TAKE CERTAIN
OTHER MEDICINES
SHOULD TALK TO THEIR DOCTOR
BECAUSE SERIOUS
STOMACH PROBLEMS
SUCH AS BLEEDING MAY WORSEN.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
SLOW HEART RATE.
THIRTY DAYS OF EXELON PATCH
FREE FOR YOUR LOVED ONE.
ACCESS TO TRAINED NURSES
FOR YOU.
CALL 1-855-999-1399
OR VISIT EXELONPATCHOFFER2.COM.
>>  AS YOU'VE BEEN HEARING
WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE
ACCUSED SHOOTER IN THESE
STORIES AND NEIGHBORS SAYING
THE YOUNG MAN MAY HAVE
SUFFERED FROM A DEVELOPMENTAL
DISORDER, POSSIBLY ASPERGER'S
SYNDROME, A HIGH FORM OF
AUTISM.
WHAT COULD IT MEAN TO THE
INVESTIGATION OR POSSIBLE
MOTIVE.
JOINING US ON THE PHONE IS DR.
MANNY ALVAREZ AND SENIOR
MANAGING EDITOR OF FOX NEWS
HEALTH.COM AND DR. MANNY,
YOU'RE THE FATHER OF A CHILD
WHO IS ON THE AUTISM SPECTRUM.
AS YOU HEAR THE REPORTS ABOUT
POSSIBLE ASPERGER'S, WHAT ARE
YOUR THOUGHTS?
>> LISTEN, THE AUTISM SPECTRUM
IS A VERY COMPLEX GROUP OF
DIFFERENT AILMENTS, BUT IN NO
WAY DOES IT HAVE AN EVIL
COMPONENT TO IT.
MOST CHILDREN WITH AUTISM HAVE
SWEET, LOVING CHILDREN AND
ASPERGER'S IN PARTICULAR, YOU
HAVE HIGH FUNCTIONING
INDIVIDUALS, VERY PRODUCTIVE.
YES, THEY HAVE STRUGGLES WITH
SOCIALIZING, WITH
COMMUNICATING, THEY'RE
NORMALLY INTELLIGENT AND IN
MANY OF TIMES EVEN THE
DIAGNOSIS IS THEY'RE FOR THE
COMMUNITY.
YOU KNOW, WE HAVE TO SEPARATE
TWO THINGS HERE WE HAVE AIDS
IN THE AUTISM SPECTRUM.
IF THEY'RE NOT TAKEN CARE OF,
IF THEY'RE IN THE IN A LOVING
ATMOSPHERE, SOMETIMES THEY'RE
EXPOSED TO UGLINESS AND COPE
WITH IT IN A DIFFERENT WAY,
BUT SOMETIMES WITH AUTISM
BECAUSE THEY'RE A LITTLE
BEHIND IN THE COMMUNICATION
SKILLS, THEY'RE NOT ABLE TO
TALK ABOUT THE UGLINESS, TO
ME, IT'S MORE THE ENVIRONMENT,
IT'S, YOU KNOW, HOW THEY WERE
RAISED, HOW THEY WERE LOVED,
WHY YOU KNOW, WHAT, WHAT, YOU
KNOW WHAT PEOPLE DID FOR THEM,
HOW THEY DEAL WITH OTHERS
MAKES THE DIFFERENCE JUST LIKE
ANY OTHER CHILD COULD BE
EXPOSE TODAY UGLINESS.
AND MY HEART, YESTERDAY WHEN
THIS WHOLE THING HAPPENED, I
HAD TO GO PICK UP MY SON AT
HIS SCHOOL, YOU KNOW, HE'S MY
AUTISTIC SON AND HE HAD
ALREADY HEARD IT,S' 15 YEARS
OLD AND WE CAME HOME AND WE
TALKED ABOUT IT AND FOR HIM, I
HAD TO EXPLAIN IT IN A
DIFFERENT KIND OF LIGHT.
>> Rick: RIGHT.
>> BUT YOU COULD SEE THAT HE
DOES UNDERSTAND, JUST LIKE ANY
CHILD IN THE SPECTRUM.
THEY UNDERSTAND GOOD AND EVIL
AND THEY UNDERSTAND THAT EVIL
DOES NOT PLAY A ROLE IN
ANYBODY'S PART.
SO, YES, I THINK THAT THE
SPECULATION IS GOING TO MOVE
FORWARD.
I THINK THAT PEOPLE ARE GOING
TO TALK ABOUT THIS PAST
HISTORY OF ASPERGER'S AND
WHETHER OR NOT HE WAS AN
OUTCAST IN HIGH SCHOOL OR NOT,
BUT AT THE END OF THE DAY, IT
IS HOW, WHAT KIND OF EVILNESS
OR WHAT KIND OF LACK OF LOVE
THAT THEY SEE GROWING UP.
>> Rick: DR. MANNY ALVAREZ A
PART OF THE NEWS MEDICAL
A-TEAM.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
>> THANK YOU.
...
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S SIMPLE PHYSICS...
A BODY AT REST
TENDS TO STAY AT REST...
WHILE A BODY IN MOTION
TENDS TO STAY IN MOTION.
STAYING ACTIVE CAN ACTUALLY
EASE ARTHRITIS SYMPTO.
BUT IF YOU HAVE ARTHRITIS,
STAYING ACTIVE
CAN BE DIFFICULT.
PRESCRIPTION CELEBREX
CAN HELP RELIEVE ARTHRITIS PAIN
SO YOUR BODY
CAN STAY IN MOTION.
BECAUSE JUST ONE
200MG CELEBREX A DAY
CAN PROVIDE 24 HOUR RELIEF
FOR MANY WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND INFLAMMATION.
PLUS, IN CLINICAL STUDIES,
CELEBREX IS PROVEN TO IMPROVE
DAILY PHYSICAL FUNCTION
SO MOVING IS EASIER.
CELEBREX CAN BE TAKEN WITH
OR WITHOUT FOOD.
AND IT'S NOT A NARCOTIC.
YOU AND YOUR DOCTOR
SHOULD BALANCE THE BENETS
WITH THEISKS.
ALL PRESCRIPTION NSAIDS,
LIKE CELEBREX, IBUPROFEN,
NAPROXEN, AND MELOXICAM
HAVE THE SAME
CARDIOVASCULAR WARNING.
THEY ALL MAY INCREASE
THE CHANCE
OF HEART ATTACK OR STROKE,
WHICH CAN LEAD TO DEATH.
THIS CHANCE INCREASES
IF YOU HAVE HEART DISEASE
RISK FACTORS
SUH AS HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE