MAGAZINES THAT HELPED LAUNCH HIS
SUCCESSFUL SKETCH SERIES.
SEVEN YEARS AND A FEW NOVELS
LATER, DICKENS BEGAN WORK ON THE
STORY OF EBENEZER SCROOGE AND A
SUPERNATURAL JOURNEY THROUGH
CHRISTMAS HAS PAST, PRESENT AND
FUTURE HE COMPLETED IT IN SIX
WEEKS AND STILL ONE OF THE MOST
POPULAR HOLIDAY STORIES OF ALL
TIME.
IT WAS FOUNDED 169 YEARS AGO
TODAY.
THAT'S THE FOX REPORT FOR
MONDAY, DECEMBER 17, 2012.
I'M JOHN SCOTT IN FOR SHEPARD
SMITH.
SHEP IS BACK TOMORROW.
"THE FACTOR" IS UP NEXT.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
>>> "THE O'REILLY FACTOR" IS ON.
TONIGHT --
>> ARE WE REALLY PREPARED TO SAY
THAT WE'RE POWERLESS IN THE FACE
OF SUCH CARNAGE?
THAT THE POLITICS ARE TOO HARD?
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA HIPTING HE
WILL SUPPORT SOME KIND OF
MEASURE TO REDUCE GUN VIOLENCE
IN AMERICA.
SO WHAT THAT MIGHT BE IS A
MYSTERY.
WE'LL TELL WHAT YOU HAS WORKED
IN SOME OTHER COUNTRIES.
>> SHE WAS THE TYPE OF PERSON
THAT COULD JUST LIGHT UP A ROOM.
SHE IS AN INCREDIBLE PERSON AND
I'M SO BLESSED TO BE HER DAD.
>> AMERICAN CHILDREN ARE 13
TIMES MORE LIKELY TO BE MURDERED
HERE THAN IN OTHER DEVELOPED
NATIONS.
WHY?
WE WILL TRY TO ANSWER THAT
QUESTION.
>> HIDING BEHIND THE SECOND
AMENDMENT DOESN'T CUT IT
ANYMORE.
IT'S TIME OUR LAWMAKERS REALIZE
THAT SOCIETY HAS CHANGED.
>> IT TOOK JUST MINUTES FOR SOME
FAR LEFT PUNDITS TO EXPLOIT THE
TERRIBLE MURDERS IN CONNECTICUT
FOR POLITICAL PURPOSES.
BERNIE GOLDBERG WILL HAVE
THOUGHTS ON THAT.
CAUTION.
YOU ARE ABOUT TO ENTER THE NO
SPIN ZONE.
"THE FACTOR" BEGINS RIGHT NOW.
>> HI.
I'M BILL O'REILLY.
THANKS FOR WATCHING US TONIGHT.
WHAT DO WE DO, WHAT DO WE DO
ABOUT VIOLENT EVIL?
THAT IS THE SUBJECT OF THIS
EVENING'S TALKING POINTS MEMO.
HAVING DONE EXTENSIVE RESEARCH
ON LEE HARVEY OSWALD FOR
"KILLING KENNEDY," I SNOW
SOMETHING ABOUT VIOLENT EVIL I.
SAW IT FIRSTHAND IN EL SALVADOR
AND THE MIDDLE EAST AND I SAT
ACROSS ELECTRIC IT WHEN I
INTERVIEWED A FORMER SS GUARD
WHO WORKED AT THE CONCENTRATION
CAMP IN GERMANY.
SO WHEN I FIRST HEARD THAT
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA HAD
MURDERED 27 PEOPLE, INCLUDING 20
LITTLE CHILDREN, I PRETTY MUCH
KNEW A FEW THINGS ABOUT LANZA.
NUMBER ONE, THAT HE WAS DEEPLY
ANGRY.
NUMBER TWO, THAT HE WAS
ALIENATED FROM MOST OTHER HUMAN
BEINGS.
NUMBER THREE, THAT MOST LIKELY
HE WAS DEEPLY INVOLVED WITH THE
INTERNET.
ALL OF THOSE THINGS HAVE NOW
BEEN ESTABLISHED.
ADAM LANZA COULD NOT LIVE HIS
LIFE IN A NORMAL WAY.
THERE HAS BEEN SPECULATION THAT
HE HAD ASPERGERS SYNDROME, BUT
THAT HAS NOT BEEN ESTABLISHED
AND THAT IS UNFAIR TO KNOWS WHO
HAVE THAT PERSONALITY DISORDER,
OR AUTISM, TO DIAGNOSE HIM
WITHOUT CONCLUSIVE PROOF.
I GIVE MONEY TO AUTISM CHARITY.
VERY FEW PEOPLE WHO HAVE THAT
CONDITION ARE VIOLENT.
THEY HAVE ENOUGH TO DEAL WITH.
THEY DON'T NEED TO BE
STIGMATIZED.
LET'S GET BACK TO LANZA.
WHAT CAN BE DONE ABOUT PEOPLE
LIKE HIM?
THE ANSWER IS VERY LITTLE.
WE'RE A REACTIVE SOCIETY IN
AMERICA.
OUR FREEDOMS DICTATE THAT WE CAN
NOT WAREHOUSE PEOPLE OR STRANGE.
THEY MUST COMMIT A CRIME OR DO
SOMETHING DESTRUCTIVE BEFORE
THEY CAN BE TAKEN INTO CUSTODY.
APPARENTLY ADAM LANZA DID NOT DO
THOSE THINGS UNTIL THE DAY HE
COMMITTED MASS MURDER.
SO ATTENTION TURNS TO THE GUNS
LANZA TOOK FROM HIS MOTHER WHOM
HE KILLED BEFORE THE SCHOOL
RAMPAGE.
THERE IS NO QUESTION THAT
AMERICA DOES HAVE A GUN CULTURE.
RIGHT NOW THERE ARE NEARLY
300 MILLION GUNS IN CIRCULATION
IN THIS COUNTRY.
CHILDREN AGES FIVE TO 14 ARE 13
TIMES AS LIKELY TO BE MURDERED
WITH GUNS HERE AS CHILDREN IN
OTHER INDUSTRIALIZED NATIONS.
LAST YEAR MORE THAN 18,000
PEOPLE COMMITTED SUICIDE WITH A
FIREARM IN THIS COUNTRY.
MORE THAN 8,000 WERE MURDERED
WITH GUNS.
SIMPLY PASSING LAWS AGAINST GUN
POSSESSION WILL NOT STOP MASS
MURDER.
IT WOULD BE LIKE ENGLAND BANNING
KNIVES AFTER JACK THE RIPPER'S
KILLING SPREE.
U.S. CONSTITUTION ALLOWS
AMERICANS THE RIGHT TO ARM
THEMSELVES, NO QUESTION ABOUT
THAT.
BUT WE CAN NOW EXPECT PRESIDENT
OBAMA TO GET BEHIND LEGISLATION
THAT WOULD LIMIT WHAT KIND OF
FIREARMS THE PUBLIC CAN BUY.
>> ARE WE REALLY PREPARED TO SAY
THAT WE'RE POWERLESS IN THE FACE
OF SUCH CARNAGE, THAT THE
POLITICS ARE TOO HARD?
ARE WE PREPARED TO SAY THAT SUCH
VIOLENCE VISITED ON OUR CHILDREN
YEAR AFTER YEAR AFTER YEAR IS
SOMEHOW THE PRICE OF OUR
FREEDOM?
>> THE PRESIDENT SPEAKING LAST
NIGHT IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
HE DID NOT SPECIFICALLY SAY HE
WOULD CALL FOR STRICTER CONTROLS
ON HEAVY WEAPONS LIKE THE AR 15
RIFLE LANZA USED.
BUT IT'S CLEAR HE IS HEADING IN
THAT DIRECTION.
BUT BEFORE CONGRESS TAKES ANY
ACTION, IT SHOULD STUDY THE
SITUATIONS IN EASTERN EUROPE AND
RUSSIA WHERE MOST GUNS ARE
BANNED.
HASN'T CUT DOWN ON GUN VIOLENCE,
HOWEVER.
AS THOSE COUNTRIES HAVE A HIGHER
MURDER RATE THAN THE USA.
ALSO THE GUN MURDER RATE HERE IN
AMERICA HAS ALMOST BEEN CUT IN
HALF IN THE PAST 20 YEARS.
TALKING POINTS WANTS A SANE
COUNTRY WITH SMART PUBLIC SAFETY
MEASURES.
DO WE NEED SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLES
TO BE EASILY AVAILABLE?
THAT'S A WORTHY DEBATE.
AND THERE ARE STRONG POINTS ON
EACH SIDE.
CLEARLY WE THE PEOPLE, HAVE TO
TAKE A TOUGH LOOK AT OUR VIOLENT
SOCIETY AND FIND SOME EFFECTIVE
SOLUTIONS WITHOUT VIOLATING
CONSTITUTIONAL RIGHTS.
A VERY DIFFICULT SITUATION, BUT
WE HAVE TO TRY.
THAT'S A MEMO.
NOW FOR THE TOP STORY, REACTION.
JOININGS FROM PHOENIX, ALAN
GOTTLIEB, FOUNDER OF THE SECOND
AMENDMENT FOUNDATION, NATIONAL
RIFLE ASSOCIATION, WOULD NOT
PROVIDE, WOULD NOT PROVIDE A
SPOKESPERSON THIS EVENING.
SO DO YOU HAVE ANY GIVE AT ALL?
IS THERE ANY AREA THAT YOU WOULD
COMPROMISE AS FAR AS NEW LAWS
MAKING IT MORE DIFFICULT TO
OBTAIN CERTAIN WEAPONS?
>> FIRST, BILL, LET ME SAY I
THOUGHT YOUR TALK POINTS WERE
REALLY EXCELLENT.
>> THANK YOU.
>> IF YOU TAKE A LOOK AFFIDAVIT
THE DATA HERE, WE BANNED ASSAULT
RIFLES ONE TIME IN 1994.
IF YOU LOOK AT THE NATIONAL
INSTITUTE OF JUSTICE'S STUDY ON
THAT BAN THAT WAS DONE IN 1999,
AS WELL AS THE UNIVERSITY STUDY
AT THE UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA
BERKELEY, HARDLY A BASSTIVE
PRO-GUN RIGHTS THOUGHT, IT
SHOWED IT HAD NO IMPACT AT ALL
ON LOWERING HOMICIDE RATES.
IN FACT, IT HAD NO IMPACT AT ALL
ON LOWERING MASS MURDERS.
IN THE NUMBER OF BULLETS THAT A
VICTIM WAS SHOT WITH.
SO THE TRUTH IS WE ALREADY KNOW
IT DOESN'T WORK.
BUT WHEN WE TRIED IT LAST TIME,
WHAT HAPPENED?
WE HAD A TEN-YEAR SUPPLY OF ALT
WEAPONS SOLD IN ONE YEAR BEFORE
THE BAN COULD GO INTO EFFECT AND
WHEN IT WAS ENACTED AND BECAME
EFFECTIVE.
BOTTOM LINE IS WE'RE GOING TO
SEE THAT AGAIN THIS TIME, TOO.
AS EVERYBODY CALLS FOR BANNING
THESE GUN, YOU'LL SEE RECORD
SALES OF THESE FIREARMS.
SO I DON'T THINK IT'S WHAT THE
ANTIGUN PEOPLE WANT TO DO.
>> I DON'T DISAGREE WITH YOU AS
FAR AS THE STUDY AND THE DATA
AND ALL OF THAT.
BUT WHY DOES AN INDIVIDUAL NEED
AN AK 15?
MAYBE NEEDS NOT THE BEST WORD.
WOULD IT BE BETTER,
MR. GOTTLIEB, FOR AMERICANS TO
SAY YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'D LIKE TO HAVE TARGET PRACTICE
WITH THIS AND I'D LIKE TO GO
HUNTING WITH THAT.
AND IT'S A WEAPON THAT I'D LIKE
TO HAVE.
BUT FOR THE GREATER GOOD, I'M
GOING TO GO ALONG -- THIS IS
WHAT'S COMING DOWN AND YOU KNOW
IT'S COMING DOWN.
I'M GOING TO GO ALONG WITH THAT.
HAND GUNS I SAY NORTH TEXAS
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
I MEAN, WE NEED -- WE THE PEOPLE
DOINGNEED THE ABILITY TO PROTECT
OURSELVES.
AN AK 15, I'M NOT SURE WE NEED
THAT.
>> WELL, IT'S AN AK 47 AND AR
15, IT'S EASY TO CONFUSE.
>> I'M SORRY.
>> I WANT TO GET YOU RIGHT ON
THAT.
WE SAW -- I LIKE TO POINT OUT ON
NATIONAL TELEVISION, WE SAW FILM
FOOTAGE OF KOREAN MERCHANTS
USING THESE TYPES OF FIREARMS ON
TOP OF THEIR ROOF TOPS DURING
THE L.A. RIOTS SO PLAYER PLACE
OF BUSINESSES WEREN'T LOOTED.
WE WATCHED DURING HURRICANE
ANDREW PEOPLE USING THESE KIND
OF FIREARMS IN FRONT OF THEIR
HOMES TO STOP LOOTING AFTER THE
HURRICANE OF THE LITTLE PROPERTY
THEY HAD LEFT.
THEY'RE USING SPORT SHOOTING
HEAVILY.
THESE SPORT UTILITIES --
>> SO YOU SAY IN SOME CASES
THEY'RE NEEDED TO DEFEND -- ALL
RIGHT.
THAT'S YOUR ARGUMENT.
NOW, IN AUSTRALIA --
>> WELL, GO AHEAD.
>> IN AUSTRALIA, THEY DID BAN
SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPONS AND THE
CRIME RATE PLUMMETED THERE.
AND THEY SAY IN AUSTRALIA, THAT
WAS A VERY EFFECTIVE PUBLIC
POLICY DEAL.
THAT HAPPENED IN 1996.
THEY DID A STUDY AND SAID LOOK,
HAND GUNS, OKAY.
A LITTLE STRICTER THAN HERE, NOT
SO MUCH.
CANADA, 60 DAYS TO OBTAIN A
FIREARM THERE.
THEY PUT YOU THROUGH HOOPS.
YOU GOT TO JUMP THROUGH HOOPS
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
WOULD EITHER AUSTRALIA OR
CANADA, THE DATA THERE, 'CAUSE
MUCH LOWER GUN HOMICIDE RATE IN
BOTH OF THOSE COUNTRIES -- WOULD
THAT CONVINCE YOU AT ALL?
>> WELL, NO, BECAUSE IN
AUSTRALIA, WHILE IT WENT DOWN
IMMEDIATELY AFTER THE BAN, WHAT
HAPPENED SUBSEQUENTLY IS IT WENT
BACK UP AGAIN.
>> NOT ACCORDING TO THE ANDREW
LEE OF THE NATIONAL UNIVERSITY
THERE, WHO STUDIED TEN YEARS
HOMICIDES FELL 59% AND SUICIDES
65%.
SO THAT'S THE LATEST STUDY OUT
OF THERE.
>> WELL, MORE RECENT DATA SHOWS
THAT, IN FACT, IT'S COMING WAY
BACK UP AGAIN.
PEOPLE ARE ALSO USING OTHER
WEAPONS TO COMMIT CRIMES IF
AUSTRALIA AS WELL.
>> YOU KNOW AS WELL AS I DO
THAT -- IN AUSTRALIA, HERE IT'S
3.3%.
NO MATTER WHAT YOU DO WITH THE
STATS, IT'S WAY BELOW US IN
AUSTRALIA.
THAT'S JUST A FACT.
>> THAT IS A FACT.
BUT THE UNITED STATES IS A WHOLE
LOT OF REASONS WHY WE HAVE THE
VIOLENT CRIME, NOT JUST WITH
GUNS, BUT OTHER WEAPONS AS WELL.
A LOT OF CULTURAL, ECONOMIC,
SOCIAL REASONS WHY.
>> I SEE THAT.
AND AUSTRALIA HAS ONLY
22 MILLION.
WE HAVE 320 PEOPLE.
CANADA, AGAIN, THEY HAVE
35 MILLION PEOPLE.
BUT WOULDN'T IT MAKE A LITTLE
BIT MORE SENSE JUST TO TIGHTEN
THINGS UP A LITTLE BIT?
I AM A SECOND AMENDMENT GUY.
AND I KNOW WHAT THE FOUNDING
FATHERS' INTENT WAS.
THEY WANTED AMERICANS TO BE ABLE
TO DEFEND THEMSELVES.
THERE ISN'T ANY QUESTION ABOUT
IT.
BUT I THINK WE CAN TIGHTEN IT UP
A LITTLE, MR. GOTTLIEB.
I'LL GIVE YOU THE LAST WORD.
>> BILL, LIKE YOU SAID IN YOUR
TALKING POINTS, NEW GUN LAWS
WOULDN'T PROBABLY STOP A CRIME
LIKE THIS AND YOU'RE RIGHT, THEY
WON'T.
HE BROKE AT LEAST 41 LAWS TO
BEGIN WITH.
PROBLEM HERE IS MENTAL HEALTH
LAWS IN THE UNITED STATES NEED
TO BE UPDATED AND CHANGED SO
THESE PEOPLE GET THE TREATMENT
THEY NEED AND THEY'RE NOT WALK
AROUND --
>> DID HE NOT DO ANYTHING IN 20
YEARS THAT WOULD HAVE WARRANTED
ANY KIND OF COMPULSORY MENTAL
HEALTH INTERVENTION ON HIS PART.
SO AGAIN, IT'S THE SAME THING.
>> WE'RE NOT SURE ABOUT THAT.
>> OUR RESEARCH SHOWS IT RIGHT
NOW.
NEW STUFF COULD COME IN, BUT
RIGHT NOW THERE WASN'T ANYTHING
THIS MAN DID IN 20 YEARS THAT
WOULD HAVE WARRANTED --
>> YOU'RE TALKING POINTS, YOU
REFERENCED HE WAS PRETTY
ANTISOCIAL AND DIDN'T QUITE FIT
IN.
>> THAT'S NOT ENOUGH.
>> THERE WERE WARNING SIGNS.
>> YEAH.
IF THERE WAS ANYTHING SOCIAL, IT
WOULDN'T BE ON TV, THAT'S JUST
THE WAY IT IS.
MR. GOTTLIEB, WE APPRECIATE YOUR
POINT OF VIEW AND VERY
INTERESTING DISCUSSION.
NEXT ON THE RUNDOWN, JUAN AND
MARY CATTED REPUBLICAN WILL
REACT TO THE TALKING POINTS
MEMO.
LATER, BERNIE GOLDBERG ON FAR
LEFT PUNDITS EXPLOITING THE
CONNECTICUT VIOLENCE FOR
POLITICAL REASONS.
WE'RE COMING RIGHT BACK.
[ Female Announcer ]
IF YOU CARE FOR SEONE WITH
MILD TO MODERATE ALZHEIMER'S,
YOU'LL ALSO CARE ABOUT
OUR NEW OFFER.
YOU GET ACCESS TO NURSES WHO
CAN HELP WITH YOUR QUESONS.
AND YOUR LOVED ONE CAN GE
EXELON PATCH FREE FOR 30 DAYS.
IF THE DOCTOR FEELS
IT'S RIGHT FOR THEM.
IT CANNOCHANGE
HOW THE DIASE PROGRESSES.
HOSPITALIZATION
AND RARELY ATH
HAVE BEEN REPORTED IN PATIENTS
WHO WORE MORE THAN ONE PATCH
AT A TIME.
THE MOST COMMON SIDE EFFECTS
OF EXELON PATCH
ARE NAUSEA, VOMITING,
AND DIARRHEA.
THE LIKELIHOOD AND SEVERITY
OF THESE SIDE EFFECTS
MAY INCREASE
AS THE DOSE INCREASES.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
LOSS OF APPETITE OR WEIGHT.
PATIENTS WHO WEIGH
LESS THAN 110 POUNDS
MAY EXPERIENCE
MORE SIDE EFFECTS.
PEOPLE AT RISK
FOR STOMACH ULCERS
WHO TAKE CERTAIN
OTHER MEDICINES
SHOULD TALK TO THEIR DOCTOR
BECAUSE SERIOUS
STOMACH PROBLEMS
SUCH AS BLEEDING MAY WORSEN.
PATIENTS MAY EXPERIENCE
SLOW HEART RATE.
THIRTY DAYS OF EXELON PATCH
FREE FOR YOUR LOVED ONE.
ACCESS TO TRAINED NURSES
FOR YOU.
CALL 1-855-999-1399
OR VISIT EXELONPATCHOFFER2.COM.
SURE. CE OR PIE?
PIE.
APPLE OR CHERRY?
CHERRY.
OIL OR CREAM?
OIL OR CREAM
CREAM.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] THE SOUND OF
REDDI-WIP ITHE SOUND OF JOY.
>> Bill: HOW TO MITIGATE GUN
VIOLENCE, JOINING US, MARY
KATHERINE HAM AND JUAN WILLIAMS.
I APOLOGIZE FOR THE AUDIENCE FOR
MIXING UP AN AK AND AR 15.
I'M NOT A GUN GUY, BUT I'M NOT
TOTALLY IGNORANT ABOUT THE
ISSUE, IT'S JUST THAT -- I MADE
A MISTAKE.
SO NOW I LOOK LIKE AN IDIOT, BUT
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
JUAN, YOU HEARD THE DISCUSSION.
YOU HEARD THE TALKING POINTS.
I'M PUTTING YOU IN CHARGE NOW.
YOU'RE PRESIDENT OBAMA'S TOP
ADVISOR ON THIS ISSUE.
YOU TELL HIM TO DO WHAT?
>> YOU KNOW, FIRST OF ALL, I
REALLY APPRECIATE YOUR TONE
TONIGHT.
I THINK THAT YOU HAVE AMERICA'S
HEART BECAUSE THIS IS CHRISTMAS
SEASON AND THE IDEA OF THOSE
LITTLE KIDS --
>> Bill: WE WANT TO PROTECT THE
KIDS ON EVERY LEVEL AND IF WE
HAVE TO ALL SACRIFICE A LITTLE
BIT, I THINK WE SHOULD.
IT'S A COMPLICATED ISSUE.
MR. GOTTLIEB WAS AN EXCELLENT
GUEST, BY THE WAY.
HE PUT FORTH HIS POINT OF VIEW
WITH FACTS, NOT EMOTION.
WASN'T SOME WINGO GUY.
YOU GOT TO TAKE THAT SERIOUSLY.
>> I DO.
I MEAN, I THINK YOU WERE RIGHT
WHEN YOU CITED THOSE NUMBERS
ABOUT THE DIFFERENCE IN LEVELS
OF HOMICIDE BY GUN IN THE U.S.,
AUSTRALIA, AND YOU CAN LOOK AT
OTHER DEVELOPED COUNTRIES.
YOU MENTIONED CANADA.
IT'S SIMILAR.
THE THREE THINGS I WOULD DO
RIGHT AWAY, ONE IS I THINK THE
GOVERNMENT SHOULD BE FREE TO
SHARE INFORMATION IN TERMS OF
BACKGROUND CHECKS.
THE GUY THAT DID THE SHOOTING IN
VIRGINIA, VIRGINIA TECH, THAT
STATE JUDGE HAD FOUND HIM
MENTALLY INCOMPETENT.
BUT GUESS WHAT?
THE PEOPLE WHO WERE SELLING GUNS
DIDN'T HAVE ACCESS TO THAT
INFORMATION.
>> Bill: BUT YOU'RE ASKING FOR A
MASSIVE BUREAUCRACY OF
360 MILLION PEOPLE.
>> NO I'M NOT.
>> Bill: I WANT INFORMATION TO
BE SHARED AS WELL.
>> OKAY.
>> Bill: IF YOU THINK THIS KIND
OF A SYSTEM OF INFORMATION
SHARING IS GOING TO WORK AT ALL
LEVELS, IT'S JUST NOT.
>> I THINK IT COULD.
I THINK IT'S AN IMPROVEMENT.
YOU SAID LET'S TAKE SMALL STEPS.
LET'S DO THINGS WE AGREE ON.
>> Bill: THE THING IS THE AR 15.
I MEAN, DO WE PUT RESTRICTIONS
LIKE AUSTRALIA HAS, CANADA HAS.
BRITAIN DOESN'T HAVE ANY GUNS.
YOU CAN'T HAVE ANY GUNS THERE.
>> OKAY.
THE SECOND THING IS BACKGROUND
CHECKS.
RIGHT NOW IF YOU'RE AN
UNLICENSED GUN DEALER, YOU'RE A
COLLECTOR, YOU CAN SELL A GUN TO
ANYBODY WITHOUT ANY CHECKS.
I THINK WE SHOULD HAVE STRINGENT
ENFORCEMENT OF BACKGROUND
CHECKS.
>> Bill: CAN DID HAS THAT.
60-DAY WAITING PERIOD.
IN THIS CASE, LANZA'S MOTHER
BOUGHT THE GUNS.
>> RIGHT.
NO BACKGROUND CHECK IN THE WORLD
WOULD HAVE STOPPED HIM.
>> WHAT I'M SAYING IS PART OF
THAT BACKGROUND SHOULD BE A FULL
FAMILY CHECK.
>> Bill: YOU CAN'T DO IT ALL
FAMILY CHECK, JUAN!
THAT'S --
>> WHY NOT?
>> Bill: THAT'S AN INVASION OF
PRIVACY!
>> I THINK THERE'S A RIGHT TO
PUBLIC SAFETY AND PROTECTING OUR
CHILDREN -- DID SHE.
>> Bill: WE'LL KICK IN
EVERYBODY'S DOOR AND LOOK AT --
>> THAT'S NOT GOOD.
>> Bill: THAT'S PIE IN THE SKY.
YOU SAY WHAT, MARY KATHERINE?
>> I SAY NOBODY HAS YET POINTED
OUT THE LAW THAT WOULD HAVE
PREHAVE NOTED THIS INCIDENT.
IF IT WERE THAT EASY, WE WOULD
PROBABLY PASS THAT LAW.
BUT FOR INSTANCE, CONNECTICUT
AND NEW JERSEY, THE PLACE WHERE
IS THESE GUYS MAY HAVE BEEN
BUYING OR HANGING OUT, OR THE
PERPETRATOR WAS, HAVE SOME OF
THE STRICTER GUN LAWS.
THERE IS AN ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN
IN CONNECTICUT, LIKE THE 1994
ONE.
SO I'M NOT SURE HOW NATIONALLY
ENFORCED ONE WOULD CHANGE THE
FACT BECAUSE AN AR 15 WHICH WAS
LEGAL UNDER THAT BAN.
SO I'M JUST CONCERNED, I THINK
YOU WERE VERY RIGHT, BILL, TO
POINT OUT WHEN WE'RE REACTING AS
SOCIETY, IT'S NOT BECAUSE WE'RE
NOT CARING.
IT'S BECAUSE WE HAVE THESE
FREEDOMS WHICH WE PRIZE VERY
HIGHLY.
>> Bill: THAT'S RIGHT.
THAT'S AN EXCELLENT POINT.
WE HAVE A STRUCTURE HERE.
WE HAVE A CONSTITUTION HERE
THAT'S DIFFERENT THAN GREAT
BRITAIN AND CANADA.
AND THERE IS A REASON FOR IT.
HISTORICALLY.
BUT THAT DOESN'T SOLVE THE
IMMEDIATE PROBLEM.
THE IMMEDIATE PROBLEM IS
BASICALLY THAT YOU, ANY
AMERICAN, CAN GET A
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE OR PISTOL
AND ALL THE ROUNDS YOU WANT AND
YOU CAN GET IT IN CONNECTICUT --
LOOK, CHICAGO IS THE TOUGHEST
GUN LAWS AND THEY'RE GUNNING
PEOPLE DOWN LIKE FIVE OR SIX A
DAY.
>> THE EVIDENCE IS THAT DOESN'T
WORK.
I WOULD ADD ALSO THERE WAS
LEGISLATION PASSED IN THE WAKE
OF THE VIRGINIA TECH MASSACRE
WHICH ALLOWED STATES AND THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT TO SHARE THAT
MENTAL HEALTH INFORMATION.
I DO BELIEVE IT CAN BE A CIVIL
LINTS ISSUE OR CAN BE A
BUREAUCRATIC MESS.
BUT THAT WAS ALREADY PASSED.
>> Bill: IF YOU WERE PRESIDENT
OBAMA'S ADVISOR, WOULD YOU
ADVISE HIM TO DO ANYTHING, PUT
FORTH ANY NEW LEGISLATION?
>> I THINK SOME DISCUSSION OF,
LIKE, THE TWEAKING OF THE
INTERSECTION OF MENTAL HEALTH
AND OWNING GUNS COULD BE
HELPFUL, LIKE I SAID IN THE WAKE
OF THIS PAST ONE, SOMETHING
PASSED AND IT WAS SUPPORTED BY
THE BRADY CAMPAIGN AND THE NRA.
SO YOU CAN COME TOGETHER ON
THESE THINGS.
I THINK YOU HAVE TO BE REALLY
CAREFUL.
THERE IS NOT A LOT OF EVIDENCE
THAT THESE LAWS STOP THESE
THINGS.
THESE ARE CRAZY PEOPLE INTENT ON
DOING THEM.
>> YOU KNOW, THIS IS JUST NOT
TRUE.
>> YOU'RE TAKING AWAY OTHER
PEOPLE'S ABILITIES TO DEFEND
THEMSELVES.
>> MARY KATHERINE, IF YOU'RE
SELLING GUNS IN THE WOODS OF
VERGE, BELIEVE ME, THERE BECOMES
A PIPELINE TO THE CITIES  THAT
LEADS TO THIS KIND OF CARNAGE
AND I THINK WE AS A COUNTRY HAVE
TO HAVE AN ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN
AND STOP SELLING THESE LARGE --
>> Bill: I GOT TO GO.
LET ME ASK YOU ONE QUESTION.
>> BE HONEST ABOUT THE FACT
THAT'S WHAT YOU WANT TO DO.
IN AUSTRALIA, THEY TOOK GUNS
AWAY FROM PEOPLE --
>> Bill: HOLD IT!
HOLD IT!
>> YOU OVERREACT.
>> Bill: HOLD IT.
I THINK THERE SHOULD BE A
UNIFORM THING OF ALL 50 STATES
ABOUT WHO YOU SELL TO AND
INFORMATION ABOUT GUNS.
BUT JUAN, THE THING ABOUT THE
SEMIAUTOMATIC BA 300 MILLION
GUNS HERE.
AS MR. GOTTLIEB POINTED OUT,
THEY'RE GOING TO BUY THEM AND
THEY'RE AROUND AND THE BAD GUYS
ARE GOING TO HAVE THEM AND THE
GOOD GUYS AREN'T.
>> YOU JUST CAN'T CURSE THE
NIGHT.
YOU GOT TO DO SOMETHING, BILL.
>> NOT IF IT DOESN'T WORK AND IF
YOU'RE IMPEDING OTHER PEOPLE.
>> Bill: RIGHT.
YOU DON'T MAKE IT WORSE.
VERY INTERESTING DEBATE, YOU
GUYS.
DIRECTLY AHEAD, WE'LL TAKE TO
YOU CONNECTICUT WHERE BILL
HEMMER IS REPORT AGO COMMUNITY
IN AGONY.
HE'S BEEN THERE ALL WEEKEND.
WE WILL UPDATE YOU ON THAT
AMERICAN MARINE BEING HELD IN A
MEXICAN PRISON.
THOSE REPORTS AFTER THESE
MESSAGES
I'M DOING MY OWN SLEEP STUDY.
ADVIL PM® OR TYLENOL PM.
THE ADVIL PM® GUY
IS SPENDING LESS TIME
LYING AWAKE
WITH ANNOYING ACHES AND PAINS
AND MORE TIME ASLEEP.
ADVIL PM®. THE DIFFERENCE
IS A BETTER NIGHT'S SLEEP.
YOU CAN STAY IN
AND SHARE SOMETHING...
OR YOU CAN GET OUT THERE
AND ACTUALLY SHARE SOMETHING.
♪
THE LEXUS DECEMBER TO REMEMBER
SALES EVENT IS ON.
THIS IS THE PURSUIT
OF PERFECTION.
FOR THEIR ANNUAL FOOTBALL TRIP.
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE.
TRAGICALLY, THEIR DDY
GOT SACKED BY BLACKOUTS.
BUT IT'S OUR TRADITION!
THAT'S ROUGHING
THE CARD HOLDER.
BUT WITH
THE Capital One Venture Card
YOU GET DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE.
[ cheering ]
ANY FLIGHT, ANYTIME.
THE SCOREBOARD DOESN'T LIE.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET? HUT!
I HAVE ME ON MY FANTASY TEAM.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>> Bill: PERSONAL STORY SEGMENT,
ALMOST EVERY PERSON I TALK WITH
OVER THE WEEKEND WAS DEVASTATED
BY THE MURDERS IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
YOU CAN IMAGINE WHAT IT'S LIKE
IN THAT TOWN THIS EVENING.
JOININGS FROM THE SCENE, FOX
NEWS ANCHOR BILL HEMMER.
WHAT'S THE MOST IMPORTANT THING
TO YOU THAT YOU SAW TODAY?
>> WOW.
I GUESS WHAT I'M LEARNING ABOUT
THE KILLER.
THE FIRST RESPONDERS AND THE
KILLER'S MOTHER.
LET'S TAKE THE FIRST THING.
WHAT I AM TOLD IS THAT ADAM
LANZA WAS WELL-KNOWN IN THIS
TOWN OF SANDY HOOK.
HE WAS ALWAYS THE KIND OF PERSON
WHO JUST DID NOT FIT IN.
THERE WERE PEOPLE WHO TOLD ME
THAT HE WOULD STOP ON A SIDEWALK
AND STARE AT YOU AND STARE AT
YOU AND STARE AT YOU MORE UNTIL
YOU WENT AND PASSED BY.
SOCIAL SETTINGS, HE RARELY, IF
EVER, TALKED.
SO YOU CAN IMAGINE IF YOU'RE A
TEEN-AGER GROWING UP HERE
ENCOUNTERING THIS YOUNG MAN, HOW
DO YOU REACT AND RESPOND TO HIM?
PART OF THAT, I THINK, HELPED TO
PUSH HIM FURTHER INTO ISOLATION.
THIS POINT IS KEY, BILL.
HE HAD NO CRIMINAL RECORD.
NONE.
EVER THAT THE POLICE TOLD US
TODAY.
>> Bill: RIGHT.
THAT'S A SMALL TOWN.
IF HE WERE CAUSING TROUBLE ON
ANY LEVEL, BUT YOU CAN'T ARREST
SOMEONE FOR STARING AT YOU.
HE WAS A WEIRDO.
THERES NO DOUBT ABOUT IT.
AND NOW WE FIND OUT HE WAS
DEEPLY INVOLVED WITH THE NET,
WHICH IS ALWAYS A PROVOCATIVE
SITUATION.
WHAT IT YOU LEARN ABOUT THE
MOTHER?
>> THE MOTHER, REMEMBER ON
FRIDAY WHEN THERE WERE ALL THESE
REPORTS SHE WAS A TEACHER AT THE
SCHOOL AND THAT --
>> Bill: THEY WEREN'T TRUE.
>> SHE NEVER TAUGHT HERE.
NOW THEY'RE SAYING HE HAD NO
CONNECTION TO THE SCHOOL.
HOWEVER, AT LEAST TWO PEOPLE
STRONGLY CONNECTED TO THE POLICE
DEPARTMENT HERE IN NEWTOWN TELL
ME THAT SHE VOLUNTEERED AT THE
SCHOOL.
NOW, DID SHE TEACH THESE KIDS IN
THAT FIRST GRADE CLASSROOM?
THAT'S NOT CONFIRMED.
HOW OFTEN DID SHE DO IT?
WHAT CLASS DID SHE TEACH?
WE CANNOT SAY.
BUT SHE APPARENTLY DID HAVE A
CONNECTION AND THAT WAS THROUGH
THE VOLUNTEER WORK SHE DID.
I MENTIONED THAT, BILL, 'CAUSE
THAT COULD BE A CRITICAL POINT
OF EVIDENCE IN TRYING TO TIE THE
SHOOTER TO THE SCHOOL BEHIND ME
HERE.
>> Bill: THE FUNERALS HAVE
BEGUN, WHICH JUST MAKES
EVERYTHING -- COMPOUNDS THE
GRIEF.
BUT FROM WHAT I UNDERSTAND FROM
WATCHING FOX NEWS ALL DAY TODAY,
THE TOWN IS HANDLING IT AS WELL
AS ANYBODY COULD HANDLE IT,
RIGHT?
THERE ISN'T ANY KIND OF LASHING
OUT OR ACTING OUT.
THERE IS NONE OF THAT.
THEY'RE VERY DIGNIFIED PEOPLE.
>> YEAH.
SO FAR I AGREE WITH YOU
ENTIRELY.
YOU KNOW THE STAGES.
SHOCK AND THEN GRIEF.
THEY'RE IN GRIEF NOW.
THEN IT'S ANGER.
I DON'T THINK WE'VE REALLY SEEN
THE THIRD PHASE OF THAT.
BUT WHAT I'VE LEARNED ABOUT SOME
OF THE FIRST RESPONDERS WHO
ARRIVED ON SCENE AT 9:30 IN THE
MORNING, ONE WAS A U.S. MARINE
WHO SERVED TWO TOURS OF DUTY IN
AFGHANISTAN.
HE'S IN HIS MID 20S.
HE'S NOT TALKING YET AND PERHAPS
WILL NOT FOR SOME TIME.
HE IS TELLING HIS CLOSE FRIENDS,
BILL, THAT WHAT HE FOUND INSIDE
THAT CLASSROOM, FAR EXCEEDS
ANYTHING HE SAW IN WAR IN
AFGHANISTAN, THE MOUNTAINS OF
THE DESERTS OF THAT COUNTRY,
OVER TWO DIFFERENT TOURS OF
DUTY.
YOU IMAGINE THE HELP THAT MAN IS
GOING TO NEED FOR THE REST OF
HIS LIFE BASED ON WHAT HE SAW
INSIDE.
THE OTHER THING I WANT TO PASS
ON TO YOU AND YOUR VIEWERS,
BILL, LATE ON SATURDAY NIGHT, I
WAS IN ONE OF THE RESTAURANTS
HERE AFTER A LONG DAY OF WORK.
THE WOMAN SITTING NEXT TO ME,
SHE WAS ABSOLUTELY INCONSOLABLE,
BILL.
I MEAN, THE TEARS RUNNING DOWN
HER FACE AND LOOKING AT US AND
TELLING, YOU'RE CRYING JUST AS
MUCH AS I AM.
YOU'RE HURTING JUST AS MUCH AS I
AM.
AND I PUT MY ARM AROUND HER AND
I SAID, LOOK, AMERICA IS CRYING
WITH YOU.
BUT THEN THE MAN NOKES TO HER,
HE WAS JUST STARING OFF IN THAT
100-YARD STARE WITH TEARS
ROLLING DOWN HIS FACE AND THE
WOMAN NEXT TO HIM DOING THE SAME
THING.
THEN WE'D WALK OUT.
ANOTHER GROUP CAME IN AND THEY
WERE DOING THE SAME THING.
THIS IS A TOWN IN ABSOLUTE
MOURNING.
IT IS A TOWN YET AGAIN THAT YOU
FIND IN TEARS.
TWO MORE FUNERALS TOMORROW,
BILL.
>> Bill: ALL RIGHT.
AND WE'RE GOING TO DO SOME
FOLLOW-UP REPORTING ON THE
CHILDREN WHO SURVIVED AND THERE
ARE GOING TO BE GRIEF
COUNSELORRERS THERE AND THE
STATE OF CONNECTICUT AND THE
GOVERNOR DOING A GREAT JOB.
THEY'RE ALL GOING TO MOBILIZE TO
HELP EVERYBODY.
WE APPRECIATE T. THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
PLENTY MORE AHEAD AS "THE
FACTOR" MOVES ALONG.
WE'LL UPDATE YOU ON THE FORMER
MARINE INCARCERATED IN THE
FILTHY MEXICAN PRISON FOR
ABSOLUTELY TO REASON.
YOU CAN SEE HIM CHAINED.
PUTTING PRESSURE ON OUR
GOVERNMENT TO GET HIM RELEASED.
THEN BERNIE GOLDBERG ON SOME FAR
LEFT PUNDITS EXPLOITING THE
AWFUL SITUATION IN CONNECTICUT.
WE HOPE YOU STAY TUNED TO THOSE
REPORTS.
I ALWAYS WAIT
UNTIL THE LAST MINUTE.
CAN I STILL SHIP A GIFT
IN TIME R CHRISTMAS?
YEAH, SURE YOU CAN.
GREAT.
WHERE'S YOUR GIFT?
UH...
WHEW.
[ Male Announcer ]
BREAK FROM THE HOLIDAY STRESS.
SHIP FEDEX EXPRESS
BY DECEMBER 22ND
FOR CHRISTMAS DELIVERY.
♪ BUT THE FIRE IS
SO DELIGHTFUL ♪
NOTHING MELTS AWAY THE COLD
LIKE A HOT, DELICIOUS BOWL
OF CHICKEN NOODLE SOUP
FROM CAMPBELL'S.
♪ LET IT SNOW, LET IT SNOW
>> Bill: FACTOR FOLLOW-UP.
JON HAMMER PROUDLY SERVED IN
IRAQ AND AFGHANISTAN REMAINS
INCARCERATED IN MEXICO TONIGHT.
HIS MOTHER SENT US THIS PICTURE
TODAY SHOWING CORPORAL HAMMAR
CHAINED TO HIS PRISON BED, JUST
ACROSS THE BORROWED PROSECUTOR
BROWNSVILLE, TEXAS.
AS WE REPORTED LAST WEEK, HE IS
BEING HELD ON A BOGUS GUN
CHARGE.
LAST AUGUST HE REGISTERED AN
ANTIQUE FIREARM WITH U.S.
CUSTOMS, THEN CROSSED THE BORDER
TO CHECK IN WITH MEXICAN
OFFICIALS CARRYING PAPERWORK.
THEY PROMPTLY ARRESTED HIM AND
THE OBAMA ADMINISTRATION HAS NOT
BEEN ABLE TO GET HIM RELEASED.
THE CORPORAL WAS TAKING THE GUN
O COSTA RICA ON A HUNTING TRIP.
JOININGS FROM CALIFORNIA ON THE
PHONE, JEREMY CANOE, BEEN
NEARLY -- SPENT THREE YEARS IN A
MEXICAN PRISON ON A DRUG CHARGE.
YOU WERE CAUGHT WITH STEROIDS,
CORRECT?
>> YES.
>> Bill: AND YOU KNEW THAT BEING
DOWN THERE WITH THIS KIND OF A
SITUATION YOU WERE PUTTING
YOURSELF IN BIG-TIME RISK?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> Bill: AND THEN WHEN THEY
CAUGHT YOU AND YOU WERE
SENTENCED TO PRISON, WHAT DID
YOU FACE IN PRISON?
WHAT WAS IT LIKE THERE?
>> TO SUM IT UP FOR YOU, IT WAS
HELL.
THE LIVING CONDITIONS IN THERE
WERE BARELY UNLIVABLE.
THE PRISON I WAS IN WAS BUILT
FOR 400 PEOPLE.
THERE WAS ACTUALLY 1200 PEOPLE
IN THERE.
I WALKED INTO THE PRISON AND
THEY PUT ME BACK INTO A ROOM
WITH 60 OTHER MEXICAN PRISONERS
AND THEY DON'T GIVE YOU NO
BLANKET OR PILLOW.
THEY DON'T GIVE YOU ANY CLOTHES,
NO TOOTHBRUSH, TOILET PAPER,
NOTHING.
YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY GIVEN NOTHING.
YOU'RE JUST BASICALLY THROWN IN
THERE LIKE AN ANIMAL.
THAT'S HOW IT WAS.
>> Bill: WHAT WAS THE STRUCTURE?
WERE THERE GUARDS, A WARDEN?
WAS THERE EXERCISE?
FOOD?
WHAT WAS ALL THAT?
>> NEVER SAW THE WARDEN.
THERE WERE -- YES, THERE WERE
GUARDS THERE.
THE GUARDS THERE WERE MOST OF
THEM WERE PRETTY CORRUPT.
THEY WOULD BRING YOU ANYTHING
THAT YOU BASICALLY WANTED INTO
THE PRISON.
IF YOU WANTED MONEY BROUGHT IN
OR FOR SOME PEOPLE DRUGS AND
STUFF LIKE THAT.
BASICALLY WHAT HAPPENED WAS AT
6:00 O'CLOCK IN THE MORNING,
THEY WOULD OPEN UP THE CELLS.
EVERYONE WENT O A BIG FREE FOR
ALL ALL DAY LONG, RUNNING AROUND
THE PRISON.
YOU KNOW, LIKE I SAID, THERE WAS
11, 1200 PEOPLE IN THERE AT A
TIME.
SO THE STATISTICS IN THERE WERE
800 PEOPLE OUT OF THE 11 OR 1200
WERE ALL DRUG ADDICTS.
>> Bill: THE GUARD WOULD SELL
THE PRISONERS DRUGS, NARCOTICS.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> Bill: HOW ABOUT THE VIOLENCE
LEVEL?
>> WELL, ON A DAILY BASIS, THERE
WERE FIGHTS.
I SAW A COUPLE MURDERS.
A COUPLE GUYS STABBED TO DEATH.
I, UNFORTUNATELY, WAS IN A
COUPLE OF FIGHTS AND WAS STABBED
TWO DIFFERENT TIMES THERE IN THE
PRISON, JUST BASICALLY OVER
MONEY.
>> Bill: DID YOU THINK YOU WERE
GOG DIE IN THERE?
>> OH, YES.
I HONESTLY THOUGHT TO MYSELF AND
I PRAYED -- I COULDN'T TELL YOU
HOW MANY PRAYERS I SAID WHILE I
WAS THERE INN THERE, LORD, JUST
GET ME OUT OF HERE.
IT WASN'T AN EVERYDAY PRAYER.
IT WAS AN ALL-DAY LONG PRAYER.
GOD, PLEASE JUST GET ME OUT OF
HERE ALIVE.
>> Bill: HOW DID THEY GET YOU
OUT?
HOW DID YOU FINALLY GET OUT?
>> WELL, AFTER THREE DIFFERENT
LAWYERS AND PAIN, THESE THREE
DIFFERENT LAWYERS, 70 TO $80,000
IN AMERICAN MONEY, NONE OF
THESE -- ONE OF THEM ACTUALLY
GOT ONE OF THE CHARGES DROPPED.
BUT I'M STILL CHARGED WITH
POSSESSION OF CONTROLLED
SUBSTANCE.
AND AFTER 70, $80,000, THEY ALL
TOOK THE MONEY AND RAN.
I ACTUALLY AM THANKFUL TO MY
AUNT, MY AUNT CONSISTENTLY
CALLED THE UNITED STATES
CONSULATE.
AFTER A PERIOD OF TIME OF
CALLING THEM AND CALLING THEM
AND CALLING THEM, THEY TOLD ME I
COULD PUT IN FOR A TRANSFER AND
I PUT IN FOR A TRANSFER.
TWO YEARS, 2 1/2 YEARS AFTER I
WAS IN THERE.
AFTER I DID PUT IN THE TRANSFER,
I GOT TRANSFERRED OUT OF THERE
BY THE UNITED STATES CONSULATE.
>> Bill: SO THEY GOT YOU OUT OF
THE COUNTRY?
>> THEY GOT ME OUT OF THE
COUNTRY.
>> Bill: AFTER ALL THE PRESSURE
THAT YOUR AUNT PUT ON THEM.
THAT'S WHAT'S GOING TO HAVE TO
HAPPEN IN THE CASE OF CORPORAL
HAMMAR AND WE'LL CONTINUE TO PUT
THE PRESSURE ON.
JEREMY, THANKS VERY MUCH.
WE APPRECIATE IT.
WHEN WE COME BACK, BERNIE
GOLDBERG ON PUNISH EXPLOITING
THE CONNECTICUT SITUATION FOR
POLITICAL REASONS.
THEN WHY IS AMERICA SO VIOLENT?
WE'LL HAVE A DISTURBING ANALYSIS
OF OUR GREAT COUNTRY AND WE'LL
BE RIGHT BACK
97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
but with ADVAIR,
I'm breathing better.
So now I can be in
the scene.
ADVAIR is
clinically proven to help
significantly improve
lung function.
Unlike most COPD medications,
ADVAIR contains both an
anti-inflammatory
and a
long-acting bronchodilator
working together to help improve
your lung function all day.
ADVAIR won't
replace fast-acting inhalers
for sudden symptoms
and should not be used more
than twice a day.
People with
COPD taking ADVAIR
may have a higher chance
of pneumonia.
ADVAIR may increase your
risk of osteoporosis
and some eye problems.
Tell your doctor
if you have a heart condition
or high blood pressure before
taking ADVAIR.
If you're still
having difficulty breathing,
ask your doctor if including
ADVAIR could help
improve your lung function.
Get your
first full
prescription
free
and save
on refills
at
ADVAIRcopd.com.
>> Bill: THANKS FOR STAYING WITH
US.
I'M BILL O'REILLY.
BERNIE SEGMENT.
ON FRIDAY, IT JUST TOOK MINUTES,
MINUTES FOR SOME PEOPLE ON MSNBC
AND OTHER LIB RAT OUTLETS TO
DIRECT THE STORY IN CONNECTICUT
FROM THE HORROR TO GUN CONTROL.
>> WHEN WE TALK ABOUT GUN
VIOLENCE IN THIS COUNTRY, WE'RE
NOT TALKING ABOUT SECOND
AMENDMENT RIGHTS.
WE'RE TALKING AS I WAS
DISCUSSING WITH THE BRADY
CAMPAIGN OFFICIALS YESTERDAY,
ABOUT REASONABLE BACKGROUND
CHECKS, REASONABLE CONTROLS,
AUTOMATIC WEAPONRY AND AMMO,
MULTIPLE ROUNDS THAT CAUSE THE
GREATEST AMOUNT OF VIOLENCE.
>> Bill: JOINING US FROM MIAMI,
MR. GOLDBERG.
WE DIDN'T DO THIS ON FRIDAY.
I DON'T KNOW WHETHER I SAW
FRIDAY'S FACTOR.
BUT WE HAD THE HIGHEST RATING,
AS USUAL, ON THE CABLE NEWS
UNIVERSE.
WE HAVE DIDN'T DO ANY OF THAT
POLITICAL STUFF.
>> RIGHT.
>> Bill: BECAUSE IT JUST WASN'T
APPROPRIATE, YOU KNOW.
>> RIGHT.
>> Bill: THE FOLKS WANTED TO
KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
THEY WANTED THE FACTS AS FAR AS
WE KNEW.
AND THEY WANTED TO SEE THE
REACTION OF THE PEOPLE ON THE
SCENE.
THEY DIDN'T WANT ANY OF THIS
POLITICAL STUFF.
NOW THREE DAYS LATER YOU CAN GET
INTO IT.
SO WHEN I SAW THAT, I JUST WENT,
YOU KNOW, IT DOESN'T REALLY
MATTER WHAT IT IS, THEIR
POLITICAL AGENDA OVERRIDES EVERY
HUMANISTIC CONCERN.
AM I WRONG?
>> NO, YOU'RE NOT,
UNFORTUNATELY.
THERE SHOULD BE A REASONABLE
PERIOD OF TIME WHEN WE SIMPLY
MOURN.
TELEVISION IS OUR NATIONAL
CATHEDRAL.
IT'S WHERE WE ALL GO WHEN THERE
IS AN AMERICAN TRAGEDY.
WE GO THERE TO GRIEVE TOGETHER
AND TO WITNESS WHAT'S GOING ON
TOGETHER.
THERE SHOULD BE NO POLITICS.
AS YOU SAID, IT TOOK MINUTES FOR
SOME ON THE LEFT AND THE MEDIA
TO START IN WITH THEIR GUN
AGENDA.
BUT CONSERVATIVE MEDIA ALSO USED
THE TRAGEDY AND THE MEDIA TO
FURTHER THEIR AGENDA.
>> Bill: HOW DID THEY DO THAT?
>> I'LL GIVE TWO EXAMPLES.
THERE WAS TALK ABOUT HOW WE TOOK
GOD OUT OF THE CLASSROOM, OUT OF
THE SCHOOL ROOM, SO WE SHOULDN'T
BE SURPRISED WHEN THERE IS
CARNAGE IN THE SCHOOLS.
>> Bill: I GOT LETTERS SAYING
THAT.
>> THERE WAS TALK ABOUT HOW WE
HAVE A MILLION ABORTIONS A YEAR,
WHICH CHEAPENS LIFE, AND THAT
SOMEHOW THIS IS RELATED TO WHAT
HAPPENED.
INDIRECTLY, BUT SOMEHOW RELATED.
>> Bill: LET ME ASK YOU
SOMETHING --
>> LET ME JUST SAY, THIS BILL.
AS IF AN INSANE GUNMAN, AN
INSANE MENTALLY UNSTABLE GUNMAN
CARES ABOUT GOD AND THE
CLASSROOM OR ABORTION.
WE KNOW HE DOESN'T.
>> Bill: OKAY.
I DON'T THINK HE WAS INSANE, BY
THE WAY.
I THINK HE KNEW RIGHT FROM WRONG
AND MAYBE THAT'S WHY HE KILLED
HIMSELF.
>> MENTALLY UNSTABLE.
>> Bill: OKAY.
NOW, I DIDN'T SEE THAT LEVEL
OF -- I GOT LETTERS SAYING WHAT
DO YOU EXPECT?
YOU TAKE GOD OUT OF THE
CLASSROOM AND WE'RE A SOCIETY
THAT DOESN'T VALUE RIGHT AND
WRONG ANYMORE.
BUT I DIDN'T SEE THAT --
CERTAINLY DIDN'T HAPPEN ON THE
FOX NEWS CHANNEL.
I DIDN'T SEE IT.
>> YES, IT DID.
YES, IT DID.
>> Bill: I DIDN'T SEE IT.
>> YEAH.
>> Bill: ALL RIGHT.
>> HAPPENED ON THE FOX NEWS
CHANNEL.
>> Bill: WAS IT FRONT AND
CENTER?
'CAUSE IT DIDN'T HAPPEN ON THIS
PROGRAM AND I WAS WATCHING PRIME
TIME AND I DIDN'T SEE A LOT OF
THAT.
>> WELL, NO.
THERE IS MORE OF IT ON THE LEFT
BECAUSE -- LOOK, EVERYBODY IN
THE MEDIA HAS A ROLE.
THAT'S THE UNFORTUNATE THING.
THAT'S WHY I'M DISGUSTED WITH
BOTH SIDES.
EVERYBODY HAS A ROLE IN THE
MEDIA.
SO THE LEFT IMMEDIATELY,
IMMEDIATELY --
>> Bill: BAN GUNS.
>> YOU KNOW WHAT?
LET'S NOT LET ANY TRAGEDY GO TO
WASTE.
SO THEY IMMEDIATELY JUMP ON THIS
TO FURTHER THE AGENDA THAT
THEY'VE GOT ABOUT GUNS.
AN AGENDA, BY THE WAY, WHEN IT
COMES TO ASSAULT WEAPONS, I'LL
SAY IT, KEEP THE LETTERS -- I
DON'T WANT TO HEAR FROM YOU --
THAT I AGREE WITH.
I DON'T THINK WE NEED ASSAULT
WEAPONS IN OUR CULTURE.
I BELIEVE IN THE SECOND
AMENDMENT.
I'M NOT ANTIGUN.
BUT I THINK WE DON'T NEED THAT.
BUT THE RIGHT ALSO JUMPS ON
THESE THINGS TO FURTHER ITS
AGENDA.
BILL, I WROTE A COLUMN ON MY WEB
SITE TODAY.
IT WAS MOSTLY ABOUT THE
INCREDIBLY DIFFICULT PROBLEM OF
HOW TO DEAL WITH PEOPLE WHO ARE
WALKING TIME BOMBS WHO SIMPLY
ARE A LITTLE DIFFERENT, THEY
SEEM ODD.
WHAT DO YOU DO WITH THOSE
PEOPLE?
AND I MENTIONED IN THIS COLUMN
THAT I WAS ALSO IN FAVOR OF A
BAN ON ASSAULT WEAPONS.
ALMOST EVERY SINGLE COMMENT
AFTERWARD DIDN'T MENTION THE
MENTAL ILLNESS PART,  WHICH IS
WHAT THE COLUMN WAS ABOUT.
THEY WANT ASSAULT WEAPONS AND
YOU KNOW WHY?
THIS IS SOMETHING THAT THE BIG
NAMES AND CONSERVATIVE MEDIA
DON'T HAVE THE GUTS TO SAY OUT
LOUD.
YOU KNOW WHY THEY WANT ASSAULT
WEAPONS?
THEY DON'T WANT IT TO PROCEED
THEY CAN'T SELVES FROM COMMON
CRIMINALS.
THEY WANT IT TO PROTECT
THEMSELVES FROM THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT.
THAT'S WHAT IT'S ABOUT.
>> Bill: ALSO A LEVEL OF
PARANOIA ON THE FAR RIGHT THAT
CERTAINLY -- YOU KNOW.
THE FOUNDING FATHERS PUT THAT
CLAUSE IN THERE BECAUSE THERE
WAS FEAR BACK THEN THAT THE
GOVERNMENT WOULD TURN OPPRESSIVE
AND THAT'S A HISTORIC FACT.
>> THEY THINK BARAK OBAMA WANTS
TO TAKE THEIR GUNS AWAY AND THAT
HE'S GOING TO SEND TROOPS INTO
THEIR HOMES.
>> Bill: IF BARAK OBAMA SENDS
TROOPS INTO THE HOMES, THE
ASSAULT WEAPONS IS NOT GOING TO
HELP THEM.
THE TROOPS ARE GOING TO BE ABLE
TO GO INTO THE HOME NO MATTER
WHAT THEY HAVE.
MY TALKING POINTS I TRIED TO BE
FAIR.
AND I TRIED TO PUT FORTH A CALM
DOWN EVERYBODY, LET'S WORK ON
THIS PROBLEM SEE IF WE CAN FIND
A SOLUTION THAT ACTUAL HEE
WORKS.
I THINK THAT'S THE GOAL HERE.
THANKS VERY MUCH.
UP NEXT, WHY IS AMERICA SO
VIOLENT?
A DISTURBING QUESTION.
WE'LL TRY TO ANSWER IT UPCOMING
OKAY, HERE'S THE PLAN.
YOU HAVE A PLAN?
FIRST WE'RE GONNA
CHECK OUR BAGS FOR FREE,
THANKS
TO OUR EXPLORER CARD.
THEN, THE UNITED CLUB.
MY MOTR
WAS SO WRONG ABOUT YOU.
NEXT,
WE GET PRIORY BOARDING
ON OUR FLIGHT
I BOOKED WITH MILES.
ALL BECAUSE OF THE CARD.
AND ME.
OKAY, WHAT'S THE PLAN?
PLAN?
MM-HMM.
WE'RE ON VACATION.
THERE IS NO PLAN.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ] THE UNITED
MILEAGEPLUS EXPLORER CARD.
THE MILEAGE CARD
WITH SPECI PERKS ON UNITED.
GET IT AND YOU'RE IN.
>> Bill: AS WE TOLD YOU IN THE
TALKING POINTS MEMO, STATISTICS
PROVE THE USA IS A VIOLENT
NATION EVEN THOUGH VIOLENT CRIME
RATES ARE DROPPING.
OBVIOUSLY WE STILL HAVE FAR TOO
MANY PEOPLE DYING IN THE STREETS
FROM GUN SHOTS AND OTHER VIOLENT
ACTIONS.
HERE IS WHAT CONNECTICUT
GOVERNOR DAN MALLOY SAID.
>> THIS IS A VIOLENT WORLD.
WE ARE PARTICULARLY VIOLENT
COUNTRY WITHIN THAT WORLD.
AND IF SOMEONE WANTS TO DO AN
ACT LIKE THIS, THEY'RE GOING TO
FIND A WAY TO DO IT IF IT'S NOT
IN A BUILDING, IT COULD BE
OUTSIDE.
>> Bill: JOINING US FROM
WASHINGTON, MARY ELLEN O'TOOL,
FORMER SENIOR PROFILE WITH THE
F.B.I. AND LIEUTENANT COLONEL
DAVE GROSSMAN, RETIRED ARMY.
THE AUTHOR OF THE BOOK "STOP
TEACHING OUR KIDS TO KILL, CALL
TO ACTION AGAINST TV, GAME MOVIE
VIOLENCE."
COLONEL, I LOVE THE WAR GAMES
WHEN I WAS A KID.
I HAD GUNS, I RAN AROUND.
I WATCHED THE WESTERNS.
AS I GREW TO AN ADULT, I DIDN'T
HAVE MUCH INTEREST IN GUNS OR
VIOLENCE OR ANY OF THAT.
SO ARE YOU SURE THERE IS A
CORRELATION BETWEEN WHAT
CHILDREN SEE ON TV AND MOVIES
AND ALL OF THAT AND HOW THEY
BEHAVE?
>> BILL, WHEN I WAS A KID, WE
NEVER BUCKLED OUR SEATBELTS.
EVERY KID I KNOW NEVER BUCKLED
THEIR SEATBELTS AND WE WERE ALL
JUST FINE.
BUT BUCKLING THE KIDS IN A SEAT
IS A DARN SMART IDEA AND IT
SAVED LIVES.  WHAT WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT HERE IS A CAUSAL FACTOR IN
THE EQUATION.
I'M OUR NATION'S NUMBER ONE LAW
ENFORCEMENT TRAINER.
MORE CONTACT HOURS, MORE CONTACT
DAYS THAN ANYBODY IN AMERICA.
I GOT A BEST SELLING VIDEO
SERIES FOR CITIZENS, MENTAL
PREPARED FOR THE BATTLE.
AND WE ARE DOING WHAT THESE
VIDEO GAMES, THESE SIMULATORS,
THESE MURDER SIMULATORS, WE ARE
PROVIDING THE SAME CONDITIONING
AND THE SAME TRAINING TO
CHILDREN THAT WE PROVIDE TO
ADULTS IN HIGH QUALITY VIDEOS
AND SIMULATIONS THAT WE PROVIDE
TO MILITARY AND LAW ENFORCEMENT
IN SIMULATORS.
THESE ARE MURDER SIMULATORS.
THEY REHEARSE THE ACTION.
THERE HAS NEVER BEEN A JUVENILE
MASS MURDERER IN THE SCHOOL IN
HUMAN HISTORY UNTIL A DOUBLE
HOMICIDE IN THE LATE '70S.
TODAY JUVENILE MASS MURDERS ARE
EVERYWHERE.
>> Bill: SO YOU THINK IT'S THE
VIDEO GAME, INTERNET CULTURE
THAT'S SO INTENSE, SO PERSONAL
BECAUSE IT'S UNLIKE WATCHING TV
OR A MOVIE, SITTING IN A BIG
THEATER WITH OTHER PEOPLE.
THIS IS VERY PERSONAL, IT'S YOU
AND THE SCREEN AND YOU ARE
ACTUALLY DOING THE SHOOTING.
BUT I'LL SUBMIT TO YOU, COLONEL,
THAT 99 OUT OF 100 CHILDREN WHO
PLAY THOSE GAMES AREN'T VIOLENT
CHILDREN.
IT'S THE ONE THAT HAS SOMETHING
GOING ON THAT ACTS OUT.
>> YOU KNOW, 99 OF 100 KIDS CAN
GO A LIFETIME WITH NO SEATBELT
ON.
BUT IT'S THE ONE IN 100 THAT
DOESN'T HAVE --
>> Bill: DO YOU WANT TO BAN ALL
OF THOSE GAMES?
>> WHAT WE NEED TO DO, BILL, IS
WE NEED TO UNDERSTAND THAT THE
VERY SICKEST GAMES AND THE VERY
SICKEST MOVIES ARE VERY, VERY
SICK INDEED AND THE KIDS WHO
GAVE US JONESBORO IN THE MIDDLE
SCHOOL, COLUMBINE IN THE HIGH,
VIRGINIA TECH IN THE COLLEGES
ARE NOW ADULTS GIVING US AURORA,
COLORADO AND SANDY HOOK SCHOOLS.
>> Bill: DO YOU SEE A DIRECT
CORRELATION.
MISS O'TOOL, DO YOU THINK THAT
SOCIETY IS BECOMING MORE VIOLENT
BECAUSE OF THIS INTERNET AND
MASS MEDIA CONCENTRATION ON IT?
>> MY EXPERIENCE IS THAT THERE
ARE PEOPLE IN THE UNITED STATES
WHO HAVE A PROPENSITY FOR
VIOLENCE AND I UNDERSTAND THAT
THAT'S A STRONG STATEMENT, BUT
THAT'S BEEN MY EXPERIENCE.
>> Bill: MORE SO THAN OTHER
COUNTRIES?
MORE SO THAN AUSTRALIA AND
CANADA AND GREAT BRITAIN WHERE?
WE'RE MORE VIOLENT?
>> THE QUALITY OF OUR VIOLENCE
IS DIFFERENT AND WHEN I REALLY
TOOK NOTE OF THAT, ESPECIALLY
WHEN IT COMES TO MASS HOMICIDES,
WITH ADOLESCENTS AND YOUNG
ADULTS IS FOLLOWING COLUMBINE.
THAT REALLY PRESENTED A NEW
NORMAL FOR US.
AND THAT PROPENSITY FOR VIOLENCE
CAN BE EXACERBATED, CAN BE
INCREASED BY VARIABLES LIKE HOW
YOU'RE RAISED, WHAT YOU VIEW ON
TV OR VIDEO GAMES FOR A SMALL
GROUP OF PEOPLE THAT ARE
SIGNIFICANTLY BUT NEGATIVELY
INFLUENCED BY NEGATIVE STIMULI
LIKE VIOLENT VIDEOS, VIOLENT
MOVIES.
>> Bill: WHAT IS THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN A CHILD WHO HAS A
PROPENSITY FOR VIOLENCE HERE IN
THE UNITED STATES AND ONE IN
CANADA?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THE DIFFERENCE
IS.
>> LET ME GIVE YOU AN ANGLE.
STANFORD MED SCHOOL CONTROL
DOUBLE BLIND MEDICAL RESEARCH
DEMONSTRATED AND WE TURN OFF TV,
MOVIE AND VIDEO GAMES IN THE
SCHOOL, WE IMMEDIATELY CUT
VIOLENCE IN HALF.
WE RAISE TEST SCORES DOUBLE
DIGITS.
IT'S THE MOST EFFECTIVE JUVENILE
OBESITY REDUCTION PROGRAM EVER
DEMONSTRATED.
HERE IS SOLID RESEARCH THAT'S
BEEN REPLICATED IN ENTIRE SCHOOL
DISTRICTS.
>> Bill: THEY HAVE THOSE
STIMULATION FACTORS IN CANADA
AND AUSTRALIA AND GREAT BRITAIN.
>> THEY DO.
CANADA HAD ALBERTA.
THIS IS A WORLD WIDE PHENOMENON.
WHEREVER THERE IS A MEDIA
VIOLENCE, THIS IS NOT JUST
AMERICA.
IN BELGIUM, A SICKO GOT IN THE
DI CARE CENTER WITH A BUTCHER
KNIFE AND HACKED 12 LITTLE
BABIES IN CRIBS.
>> Bill: IT JUST SEEMS THAT WE
HAVE MORE OF A CONCENTRATION OF
IT HERE.
ALL RIGHT.
VERY INTERESTING DISCUSSION.
I'M GOING TO CONTINUE IT.
I'VE GOT TO BREAK NOW.
I'LL BRING YOU GUYS BACK.
THANK YOU.
FACTOR TIP OF THE DAY.
WHETHER THE WAR ON CHRISTMAS IS
LEGIT.
THE TIP 60 SECONDS AWAY
This holiday, Share Everything.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
>> THE TIP OF THE WHAT YOU
THINK OF THE CHRISTMAS TREE
REPORTING.
WE ARE EXTENDING THE AMAZING
WORD PROMOTION AND IF YOU BUY
ANY ONE OF MY THREE BEST
SELLERS.
YOU GET THIS BOOK FREE.
YOU GET TWO GIFTS FOR A MODEST
PRICE AND IF YOU GET BILL O'
REILLY.
AND THAT IS TWO GIFTS AND THRU
G. AND SPEND MORE THAN $20.
WE'LL SEND YOU THIS BUMPER
STICKER FREE OF CHARGE .
BILL, YOU ARE USING LAY MAN'S
PERCEPTION OF RUMOR.
EVIL PEOPLE DON'T SEEK TO BE
CAUGHT.
THAT IS NOT THE CASE OF THE
KILLER IN.
AND HE WOULD HAVE REACTED
VIOLENTLY AND HE HAD THE
OPPORTUNITY.
I DON'T LIKE TO USE THE WORD
EVIL.
IT TRIVALIZES SOMETHING WE
NEED TO UNDERSTAND.
>> WHY SAVAGES ARE KILLED IN
CAMBODIA AND THE ENTHIRE THIRD
REICH.
UNTIL THEN EVIL WILL SUFFICE.
HORRIFIC SCHOOL KILLINGS
HAPPENED IN BATH, MICHIGAN
WHEN A MAN USED DYNAMITE TO
KILL 45.
HOW MANY MORE CHILDREN HAVE TO
DIE BEFORE AMERICA MENDS GUN
LAWS.
>> BRINGING FIRE ARMS IN
MEXICO IS A HUGE CRIME.
THAT'S WHY YOU CHECKED N. I AM
ANGRY ABOUT THE STORY.
MY WIFE AND I CANCELLED A TRIP
TO MEXICO.
IF CORPORAL HAMMER IS NOT
RELEASED BEFORE CHRISTMAS, I
THINK YOU WILL HAVE COMPANY.
THE TIP OF THE DAY, BECAUSE OF
THE COVERAGE.
DO YOU BELIEVE THAT THE FACTOR
CHRISTMAS COVERAGE IS ACCURATE
OR OVER FLOWN.
25,000.
AND 91 SAY ACCURATE.
NIPE