IT ALL STARTS RIGHT NOW ON
"THE CHEW."
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> THE OTHER WAY.
[ LAUGHTER ]
THANK YOU!
GOOD AFTERNOON.
WELCOME TO "THE CHEW."
AMERICA, HOLD ON TO YOUR
STOCKINGS.
CHRISTMAS IS EXACTLY ONE WEEK
AWAY.
AND SINCE CHRISTMAS IS THE
PERFECT TIME TO BRING HAPPINESS
TO OTHERS, PUT A SMILE ON YOUR
FAMILY'S FACES BY SERVING UP THE
MOST MOUTHWATERING COMFORT FOOD
THAT CHRISTMAS HAS TO OFFER.
IT'S TIME FOR OUR COZY
CHRISTMAS, Y'ALL!
COZY CHRISTMAS.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> YEAH!
>> WELL, CHRISTMAS IS -- AS I
JUST SAID, IT'S A WEEK AWAY.
DO YOU GUYS KNOW WHAT YOU'RE
COOKING?
DO YOU KNOW WHAT YOUR PLANS ARE?
MARIO!
>> I GOT IT DOWN SINCE AUGUST.
I'VE HAD THE PLAN.
>> SINCE AUGUST.
>> OVERACHIEVER.
>> I JUST LOVE -- HAVING A
LAPTOP AROUND, YOU JUST TEND TO
DESIGN MENUS FOR THE NEXT COUPLE
OF WEEKS.
SO I DID THESE IN AUGUST.
>> OR 15 YEARS.
>> EXACTLY.
>> DO YOU REALLY MAKE MENUS ON A
REGULAR BASIS FOR YOURSELF?
>> NO, FOR HOLIDAYS.
LIKE, HOLIDAY STUFF SO YOU CAN
DO YOUR SHOPPING, GET THE
EXOTICS IN, GET THE HAM SHIPPED
FROM CONNECTICUT.
>> HOW DO YOU HAVE TIME TO DO
THIS WITH YOUR BURGEONING
EMPIRE?
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
>> I DON'T SLEEP!
[ LAUGHTER ]
NO, WE'RE HAVING HAM.
WE'RE DOING NEW ORLEANS STYLE.
WE HAVE HAM.
WE HAVE BISCUITS.
WE HAVE COLLARDS.
>> MMM!
>> NICE!
>> SWEET-AND-SOUR SWEET
POTATOES.
WE HAVE ALL KINDS OF STUFF THAT
I KIND OF STOLE FROM -- YEAH,
WELL, IT'S KIND OF STOLEN FROM
EMERIL LAGASSE, MOST OF IT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
BUT IT'S BEING MADE AT MY HOUSE,
AND IT'LL BE ABSOLUTELY
DELICIOUS.
AND I EVEN PLAN OUT THE DAY
AFTER AND THE DAY AFTER AND THE
DAY AFTER.
I'M JUST --
>> MARIO ACTUALLY FLIES IN
EMERIL TO HAVE HIM COOK.
>> I LOVE THAT.
>> HOW ABOUT YOU GUYS?
ANY THEMES, LIKE "NEW ORLEANS
CHRISTMAS" FOR YOU GUYS?
>> I DON'T HAVE A THEME.
THIS IS GONNA BE AN INTERESTING
ONE FOR ME, BECAUSE MY MOM HAS
DONE CHRISTMAS DAY MY ENTIRE
LIFE.
AND THIS YEAR, MY SISTER'S
BOYS ARE, YOU KNOW, GETTING TO
THE AGE WHERE SHE WANTS THEM TO
WAKE UP IN THEIR OWN HOUSE, AND
THEY LIVE IN COLUMBUS.
SO MY MOM AND DAD ARE GOING TO
MY SISTER'S FOR CHRISTMAS EVE
AND CHRISTMAS DAY, AND I'M
ALWAYS WITH MY MOM AND DAD ON
THOSE DAYS.
LIZ AND I AREN'T GOING, BUT
WE'RE DOING CHRISTMAS EVE AT HER
MOM'S HOUSE.
HER MOM IS SOUTHERN, SO WE'RE
GONNA HAVE OYSTER STEW --
>> OOH.
>> YUM!
>> -- AND ALL KINDS OF DELICIOUS
GOODIES.
AND IT'S GONNA BE LIKE ME, LIZ,
KYLE, AND A COUPLE PEOPLE ON
CHRISTMAS DAY.
I'M GONNA MAKE MY MOM'S LASAGNA,
MAKE A HAM.
>> THAT'S SO NICE.
>> WELL, I JUST FOUND OUT THAT
I'M HAVING A NEW ORLEANS
CHRISTMAS, BECAUSE I'M GOING TO
MARIO'S.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> ONCE YOU GET PAST THE
SECURITY FENCE, IT'S ALL GOLD IN
THERE, BABY.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
>> WHAT'S GOING ON HERE WITH
THESE CUPS?
>> I SAW THIS THING, AND I
FIGURED I'D DO IT.
>> OH, WELL, THESE ARE SOME
GADGETS.
LET'S TALK -- YOU WANT TO TALK
GADGETS?
LET'S TALK GADGETS.
YEAH.
>> MARIO'S SMOKING HIS.
>> THE FIRST ONE IS THE COOKIE
SPOON.
SO THE COOKIES --
>> OH, GO ON.
I'M SORRY, CLINTON.
>> IT'S ALL RIGHT.
YES, IF YOU HAVE A HARD TIME
DUNKING COOKIES FOR SOME REASON
OR JUST WANT TO KEEP YOUR
FINGERS MILK-FREE --
>> YOU HAVE TO WORK IN SLOW,
THOUGH, WHILE THE COOKIE TAKES
ON THE MILK, OR ELSE THE COOKIE
BEGINS TO FLOAT.
>> AH.
>> WELL, THIS IS GOOD.
IT SEEMS TO WORK.
>> I LOVE THIS.
>> I LIKE IT.
>> YOU CAN ONLY USE IT FOR A
SANDWICH COOKIE, HOWEVER,
BECAUSE IF YOU TRY A CHOCOLATE
CHIP, IT WILL NOT HOLD ON.
>> I'M MAKING MY MILK CHOCOLATE.
>> AND THEN WHAT DO YOU DO?
YOU GO LIKE THIS?
>> IT'S SO WEIRD.
>> NO, IT'S A ONE-BITER AT THAT
POINT.
>> SO STRANGE.
IT LOOKS LIKE A TONGUE SCRAPER.
>> I'M NOT INTO IT.
>> I LOVE IT!
>> I DO, TOO.
>> I'M GOING AGAIN.
>> ALL RIGHT, HOW ABOUT THIS?
>> THESE I LIKE.
>> IT'S CALLED A FINGER PLATE.
SO IF YOU'RE HAVING HORS
D'OEUVRES AT A PARTY --
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> SO COOL!
>> THIS IS LIKE SOMETHING THAT
MIGHT HAVE BEEN INVENTED IN THE
'80s.
[ LAUGHTER ]
AND I DON'T THINK COOKIES WERE
THE ORIGINAL FOOD.
[ LAUGHTER ]
BUT AS AN HORS D'OEUVRE, I THINK
IT'S A FABULOUS REUSE.
>> YEAH.
>> MARIO, I THINK THIS IS, LIKE,
FOR YOUR PEOPLE.
THIS IS THE NEW PINKIE RING.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> FOR MY PEOPLE?
IS THAT AN ITALIAN SLUR?
>> IF "THE SOPRANOS" WERE STILL
ON, THEY'D BE WEARING THESE
THINGS AT CHRISTMASTIME.
HEY.
HOW YOU DOIN'?
>> I'M ALL RIGHT.
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
YOU GOT A CANNOLI?
>> YEAH, PUT A LITTLE CANNOLI ON
MY RING.
HOW YOU DOIN'?
>> SO YOU GUYS LIKE THE COOKIE
SPOON.
THE COOKIE SPOON IS $2.99 A
THE FINGER PLATES ARE $10.95 FOR
A SET OF 10.
ABOUT $1 EACH --
>> I LOVE IT.
>> -- FOR THAT LITTLE PLATE.
ALSO, HERE'S A LITTLE GADGET FOR
YOU.
THE WORLD'S LARGEST COFFEE CUP.
>> [ GRUNTS ]
>> OH, MY.
>> THAT'S HEAVY.
>> I LOVE THAT.
>> THIS CUP HOLDS 20 CUPS OF
COFFEE FOR A COST OF $39.99.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU'D DO WITH
THAT, THOUGH.
>> THAT IS THE PERFECT GIFT FOR
ME.
THAT'S MY DAY'S INTAKE RIGHT
THERE.
HOW MANY ESPRESSOS YOU THINK WE
COULD FIT IN THAT SUCKER?
>> WELL, ESPRESSO?
PROBABLY ABOUT 40 AT LEAST,
40 OR 50 ESPRESSOS.
>> YEAH, RIGHT.
>> AND THEN YOU'D HAVE TO GO TO
THE BATHROOM ALL DAY LONG.
>> BUT YOU'D HAVE THE CUP!
>> HOLD ON!
HOLD ON!
>> YOU DON'T EVEN HAVE TO LEAVE!
SYMON, HE DOESN'T EVER HAVE TO
GET OUT OF HIS CHAIR!
HE GETS HIS COFFEE.
FINISHES HIS MANEUVERS.
>> I LIKE IT FOR A PUNCH BOWL,
IF YOU DID SOME SORT OF COFFEE
FLAVOR.
>> OR HOT CHOCOLATE.
>> ALL RIGHT, YOU KNOW WHO WILL
MAKE ME FEEL WARM AND COZY,
'CAUSE WE'RE TALKING COZY
CHRISTMAS TODAY?
RANDY THE REINDEER!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
[ BELLS JINGLING ]
>> OBVIOUSLY.
>> RANDY COMES DOWN FROM ABOVE
WITH A QUESTION FROM ONE OF OUR
VIEWERS EVERY DAY OF THE HOLIDAY
SEASON.
>> GIDDY-UP, RANDY.
>> THANKS, RANDY.
[ BELLS JINGLING ]
>> ALL RIGHT, WHAT'S THE
QUESTION TODAY, MICHAEL?
>> KAREN FROM SEATTLE ASKS --
"HOSTING 11 PEOPLE FOR CHRISTMAS
DINNER, BUT MY DINING ROOM TABLE
ONLY SEATS 6."
>> OKAY.
>> "WHAT DID I GET MYSELF INTO?
AND WHAT DO I DO?"
>> WELL, WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
YOU WERE OUT IN SEATTLE, FOR THE
FIRST THING?
BORN AND RAISED THERE.
NOW A NEW YORKER.
JUMP INTO SEATTLE, GET TO THE
AIRPORT, GO TO THE TAXI STAND --
"HEY, LET'S GO OVER TO 6th AND
PINE."
"IS THAT WHERE YOU WANT TO GO?"
THEY'RE A LITTLE SLOW.
SO MAYBE IF YOU DIDN'T COUNT THE
CHAIRS --
[ LAUGHTER ]
BEFORE SHE INVITED HER GUESTS.
DON'T GET ME WRONG.
I'M FROM THERE.
>> MAYBE FIVE PEOPLE WILL BE
REALLY LATE.
[ LAUGHS ]
>> WHAT ABOUT BEDOUIN-STYLE ON
THE FLOOR, LIKE A PICNIC?
>> YEAH, ON THE COUCH.
>> WHATEVER.
>> YOU MAKE THE DINING ROOM
TABLE A BUFFET.
YOU HAVE THE KIND OF FOOD YOU
CAN MOVE AROUND WITH.
YOU KNOW, I'VE DONE PLENTY OF
CATERING JOBS, AND IT'S A DINNER
OF LITTLE THINGS, AND THEY DON'T
SIT DOWN.
>> OR BUY -- I'VE BEEN TO SOME
GREAT CHEFS' AND ENTERTAINERS'
HOUSES WHERE THEY HAVE MORE
PEOPLE THAN TABLE SPACE, AND YOU
FIND A SPOT ON THE COUCH.
BUY, IF YOU CAN, THE LITTLE
COFFEE -- THE FOLD-OUT -- WHAT
DO YOU CALL THOSE THINGS?
>> TV TRAYS.
THANK YOU, CARLA HALL.
ARE VERY INEXPENSIVE.
GET SOME OF THOSE, AND YOU'VE
DOUBLED, TRIPLED YOUR SEATING.
>> BUT ALSO KEEP IN MIND IF YOU
DON'T HAVE ENOUGH ROOM FOR
PEOPLE TO SIT AT A TABLE AND
CARVE, THEN DON'T SERVE ANYTHING
THAT NEEDS TO BE CARVED.
LIKE, A BIG STEAK DOESN'T GO ON
IT.
MAYBE MORE FINGERY FOOD OR
PIECES -- THINGS THAT YOU CAN
PICK UP WITH A FORK OR A KNIFE.
>> RIGHT, THINGS THAT ARE
ALREADY CUT UP.
>> AND ON TOMORROW'S SHOW,
YOU'RE ACTUALLY SHOWING US A
PARTY YOU THREW WHERE YOU DIDN'T
QUITE HAVE ENOUGH CHAIRS FOR
EVERYBODY.
>> EXACTLY.
I HAVE ONE CHAIR IN MY
APARTMENT, SO I NEEDED CHAIRS.
>> OR CLINTON'S MEAL IN A
BLENDER WORKS VERY WELL, TOO.
>> YEAH.
STILL REPEATING ON ME A LITTLE
BIT.
>> KEEP IN MIND, I STILL LOVE
YOU OUT THERE, SEATTLE.
>> YEAH, OH --
>> LOVE THAT.
>> YOU DUG THAT GRAVE, MARIO.
YOU DUG THAT GRAVE.
>> I LOVE SEATTLE.
>> YOU'RE GONNA LOVE VISITING
NOW.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> CAB DRIVERS JUST GO WHIZZING
BY.
>> A LITTLE BIT LATER IN THE
SHOW, WE'VE GOT "CLINTON'S
WORKSHOP."
WE'RE GONNA MAKE SOME HOLIDAY
ORNAMENTS.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> YEAH.
>> YES!
OH, THEY'RE EXCITED ABOUT THAT.
>> YEAH!
FUN!
>> WELL, I JUST WANTED TO SHOW
YOU THE CRAFTERS OF THE WEEK.
I'VE BEEN GETTING A LOT OF
TWEETS, A LOT OF FACEBOOK POSTS.
THERE'S A LOT ON "MY BITES," AS
WELL.
I WANT TO SHOW YOU SOME OF THE
THINGS PEOPLE HAVE MADE INSPIRED
BY "CLINTON'S CRAFT CORNER" OR
"CLINTON'S HOLIDAY WORKSHOP."
FIRST OF ALL, ANGELICA MADE A
PEPPERMINT TRAY, BUT SHE USED
STAR-SHAPED COOKIE CUTTERS TO
TURN THEM INTO ORNAMENTS.
ADORABLE, RIGHT?
TAMMY LEE MADE MY FUN BALL
WREATH FOR HER STEPDAUGHTER AND
DID A GREAT JOB WITH THAT.
BEAUTIFUL.
>> BEAUTIFUL.
>> SHE COULD USE THAT AT EASTER,
AS WELL, I THINK.
OKAY.
AND TINA O. -- HERE'S A PICTURE
OF TINA O. AND HER CRAFTING
BUDDIES.
THEY MADE MY DECORATIVE BOTTLES
WITH THE WORD "SNOW" SPELLED OUT
ON THEM.
THAT WAS ON "MY BITES" ON
THECHEW.COM.
>> CLINTON, YOU HAVE THE
CRAFTIEST FANS ON THE PLANET.
>> I'M SO EXCITED ABOUT IT.
PEOPLE TWEET ME, AND I'M JUST
LIKE, "YAY!
GO YOU!"
>> I ACTUALLY SAW ONE -- THE
GREAT TRAY YOU MADE WITH THE
PEPPERMINTS.
>> YEAH.
>> I SAW ONE THAT SOMEONE
TWEETED THAT THEY MADE IT WITH
CANDY CANES, LITTLE CANDY CANES,
AND THAT WAS KIND OF FESTIVE AND
FUN.
>> CUTE!
>> MANY DIFFERENT WAYS.
>> KELLY'S PEOPLE COME IN
FORCES!
>> JUST MAKE SOMETHING, FOR
CRYING OUT LOUD.
IT'S GOOD FOR YOU.
[ APPLAUSE ]
I WOULD SAY, "DON'T SIT AROUND
PICKING YOUR NOSE.
MAKE SOMETHING."
WHO HAS "THE DISH OF THE DAY"
TODAY?
>> OOH!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> IT LOOKS REALLY GOOD -- PASTA
AND -- IS IT GOAT CHEESE?
>> GOAT-CHEESE HAZELNUT PESTO
WITH KaDEE STRICKLAND.
IT'S GOING TO BE DELICIOUS.
>> OH!
KaDEE STRICKLAND WILL BE RIGHT
BACK WITH US.
DON'T GO AWAY!
"DISH OF THE DAY" COMING UP
AFTER THIS.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Announcer: COMING UP --
KaDEE STRICKLAND FROM
"PRIVATE PRACTICE" HAS JUST WHAT
THE DOCTOR ORDERED.
WHAT'S HER PRESCRIPTION FOR A
WARM COMFORT FOOD ESCAPE?
>>> PLUS, CLINTON'S FINAL THREE
TIPS FOR CHRISTMAS.
IS THIS FROSTY SNOWMAN ALREADY
HIDING IN YOUR DRAWERS?
FIND OUT IN A MOMENT.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
TYOU WOULDN'T WANT YOUR
ADOCTOR DOING YOUR JOB,
HELLO....
SO WHY ARE YOU DOING HERS?
ONLY YOUR DOCTOR CAN DETERMINE
IF YOUR PERSISTENT HEARTBURN IS
ACTUALLY SOMETHING
MORE SERIOUS,
LIKE ACID REFLUX DISEASE.
OVER TIME, STOMACH
ACID CAN DAMAGE
THE LINING OF YOUR ESOPHAGUS.
FOR MANY, PRESCRIPTION NEXIUM
NOT ONLY PROVIDES
24-HOUR HEARTBURN RELIEF,
BUT CAN ALSO HELP HEAL
ACID-RELATED EROSIONS
IN THE LINING OF YOUR ESOPHAGUS.
THERE IS RISK OF BONE FRACTURE
AND LOW MAGNESIUM LEVELS.
SIDE EFFECTS MAY INCLUDE
HEADACHE, ABDOMINAL
PAIN AND DIARRHEA.
CALL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY IF
YOU HAVE PERSISTENT DIARRHEA.
OTHER SERIOUS STOMACH
CONDITIONS MAY EXIST.
DON'T TAKE NEXIUM IF
YOU TAKE CLOPIDOGREL.
LET YOUR DOCTOR DO HER JOB.
AND YOU DO YOURS.
ASK IF NEXIUM IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
IF YOU CAN'T AFFORD
YOUR MEDICATION,
ASTRAZENECA MAY BE ABLE TO HELP.
I just served my mother-in-law
your Chicken Noodle soup
but she loved it so much...
I told her it was homemade.
Everyone tells
a little white lie now and then.
But now she wants
my recipe
[ clears his throat ]
[ softly ]
She's right behind me isn't she?
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
I'M HOME!
TOILET'S FIXED.
[ Male Announcer ]
OF ALL THE THINGS THAT HAPPEN
ON YOUR WOODEN SURFACES,
DISINFECTING
HAS TO BE ONE OF THEM.
CLOROX DISINFECTING WIPES.
GENTLE ON WOOD.
HARD ON GERMS.
CLOROX DISINFECTING WIPES.
DELICIOUS HERSHEY'S CHOCOLATEH,
WITH 30% LESS FAT?
HERSHEY'S SIMPLE
PLEASURES CHOCOLATE.
30% LESS FAT, 100% DELICIOUS.
We were going through so much
of the bargain detergent.
And the clothes
didn't look as good.
But since we switched to Tide
we use much less.
An amazing clean
for all three
of our full-grown
dependent bundles of joy.
That's my Tide,
what's yours?
A DELICIOUS NEW WAY TO GET
ESSENTIAL VITAMINS YOU NEED.
JUST BITE
INTO THE TASTY SHELL...
TO A CHEWY VITAMIN CORE
FOR A UNIQUE
MULTIVITAMIN SENSATION!
NEW CENTRUM FLAVOR BURST.
FOR A UNIQUE
MULTIVITAMIN SENSATION!
THE RICH DARK CHOCOLATE.
YORK PEPPERMINT PATTIE
GET THE SENSATION.
>> Announcer: AND NOW THE MOMENT
YOU'VE ALL BEEN WAITING FOR --
IT IS "THE DISH OF THE DAY."
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> WELCOME BACK TO "THE CHEW'S"
COZY CHRISTMAS.
THERE'S NOTHING COZIER THAN
CURLING UP ON THE COUCH AND
WATCHING YOUR FAVORITE TV SHOW.
AND SINCE OUR NEXT GUEST STARS
IN ONE OF AMERICA'S FAVORITE
SHOWS, ABC'S "PRIVATE PRACTICE,"
WE INVITED HER BACK TO OUR
KITCHEN.
PLEASE WELCOME A TRUE SOUTHERN
SWEETHEART, KaDEE STRICKLAND.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪
>> AAH!
>> GOOD TO SEE YOU.
HAPPY HOLIDAYS!
>> HI!
>> GOOD TO SEE YOU.
>> I JUST WANT TO STAY ALL DAY.
>> OH, MY GOD.
>> WELCOME HOME.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
HOW ARE YOU?
>> I AM VERY EXCITED ABOUT THIS.
>> THIS IS SOMETHING DELICIOUS
THAT WE'RE JUST PUTTING TOGETHER
AT THE LAST MINUTE.
YOU GREW UP IN GEORGIA.
WHAT KIND OF HOLIDAY FOODS WERE
ON YOUR TABLE?
>> WELL, I RECALL RECENTLY
SEEING YOUR LIST WHERE YOU HAD
THE TURKEY, THE HAM, EVERYTHING.
THAT'S EXACTLY -- IT STARTED IN
THE MORNING AT MY HOUSE.
MY MOTHER DID GRITS.
WE DID OMELETS.
WE DID THIS STUFF CALLED STICKY
BREAD, WHICH WAS INCREDIBLE, AND
THE SAUCE IS MADE OUT OF INSTANT
PUDDING AND, LIKE, BROWN SUGAR.
>> AMERICA!
EXACTLY RIGHT.
AND THEN WE WOULD GO TO MY
GRANNY'S AND THAT WAS DOWN AT
THE SWAMP, WHICH WAS ON THE FARM
BY THE RIVER AND THE WHOLE BIT,
AND WE WOULD HAVE --
>> SWAMP.
>> IT'S TRUE.
IT'S A SWAMP.
WE WOULD HAVE HAM.
WE WOULD HAVE TURKEY.
WE WOULD HAVE DRESSING.
WE WOULD HAVE, LIKE,
30 DESSERTS.
>> EXACTLY.
>> 30 DESSERTS EASILY.
AND THEN WE'D GO TO MY AUNT
HARRIET'S AT NIGHT, AND WE WOULD
DO BEEF.
>> I LOVE THE SOUTH!
>> I KNOW.
>> YOU'RE SO ORGANIZED ABOUT
CONSUMPTION OF MASS CALORIES!
>> YEAH, THE SOUTH KNOWS HOW TO
EAT.
IT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
MY MOTHER-IN-LAW IS FROM DALTON,
GEORGIA.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> SO IT'S THE SAME THING.
MAN, SHE COULD COOK, AND THEY
LIKED TO EAT THE STUFF.
I LOVE THE SOUTH!
>> AND THEN THE NEXT DAY YOU'RE
IN A FOOD COMA.
YOU MAKE A POT OF CHILI IN THE
AFTERNOON BECAUSE YOU'RE STILL
FULL FROM THE DAY BEFORE.
>> I LOVE THAT.
WELL, NOW YOU'RE MARRIED.
SO HAVE YOUR TRADITIONS CHANGED,
OR YOU STILL GO BACK TO THE
SOUTH?
>> WE TEND TO COOK OUT IN
CALIFORNIA NOW, MY HUSBAND AND
MYSELF.
>> LIGHT AND SIMPLE OR WITH THE
19 COURSES THAT YOU JUST
EXPLAINED?
>> I DO BREAKFAST.
I'LL DO WAFFLES OR PANCAKES IN
THE MORNING JUST FOR THE TWO OF
US.
AND THEN WE'LL HAVE A LIGHT
LUNCH.
AND THEN WE KIND OF GRAZE AND
HAVE PROSCIUTTO AND CHEESES AND
THINGS LIKE THAT.
AND THEN WE GO INTO OUR NICE
STEAK -- ASPARAGUS, A LITTLE
CELERY ROOT PUREE.
THAT'S THE STANDARD.
>> BEAUTIFUL.
SO YOU WANT TO MAKE THIS DISH
TOGETHER?
>> I CAN'T WAIT.
>> WE'RE GONNA MAKE AN ODD PESTO
THAT CHEF SYMON'S GONNA HELP YOU
WITH, MADE OUT OF GOAT CHEESE
AND HAZELNUTS, TRADITIONAL TO
WHERE?
PIEDMONT, WHERE HAZELNUTS ALL
COME FROM.
I KNEW YOU WERE GONNA SAY -- I
JUST DIDN'T WANT YOU TO
MISPRONOUNCE IT.
>> YEAH.
THANK YOU.
>> SO, WE'RE GONNA TAKE SOME
GOAT CHEESE, SOME HAZELNUTS,
SOME ROASTED PEPPERS THAT CHEF
SYMON'S GOING TO HELP YOU WITH,
A LITTLE BIT OF GARLIC AND OLIVE
OIL, AND PUT IT ALL IN AND MAKE
IT INTO A NICE BASE.
YOU ON THAT, CHEF?
>> I HAVE IT.
YES.
>> SO, NOW, YOU RECENTLY TOOK A
TRIP TO ITALY?
>> I DID.
>> REGALE US WITH THE TOP FACTS.
>> THE TOP FACTS.
UM, YOU CAN'T GO WRONG WHEREVER
YOU ARE IN ITALY.
THE PEOPLE ARE ABSOLUTELY
GLORIOUS.
THEY'RE ALL INCREDIBLE.
THEY DON'T WORK --
>> OH, YES, MY FAVORITE PART IN
ALL OF ROME!
>> LOOK THAT MERINGUE!
LOOK AT THAT MERINGUE IN THE
WINDOW.
IT'S LIKE AS BIG AS MY HEAD.
THAT WAS, AS YOU ADVISED, THE
FIRST MEAL WE HAD IN ROME.
ROME WAS PARADISE.
I JUST COULDN'T GET OVER IT.
I COULD LITERALLY --
>> LOOK AT HOW HAPPY YOU ARE
THERE.
>> OH!
YES.
OH, MY FIRST PASTA DISH IN
ITALY.
THAT WAS IN FLORENCE.
THAT WAS WITH LOBSTER.
AND THAT WAS AFTER WE'D ALREADY
HAD ABOUT THREE-FOURTHS OF THE
FOOD, AND I SAID, LET'S GET IT.
YOU KNOW, AND --
>> JUST DO IT.
>> WE DID.
WE DID IT.
WE DID IT JUST PROPERLY.
I MEAN, YOU CAN'T IMAGINE HOW
WONDERFUL IT IS TO GET IN A CAR
AND DRIVE THROUGH THE
COUNTRYSIDE AND TURN ON THE
RADIO AND THEN RANDOMLY YOU'LL
HEAR A COUNTRY MUSIC STATION,
WHICH I DID NOT EXPECT AT ALL,
AND THEN YOU WILL HEAR THE MOST
BEAUTIFUL OPERA, AND YOU'LL JUST
KEEP DRIVING AND DRIVING.
THE ROLLING HILLS.
>> AND IT ALL COMES TOGETHER,
AND NEXT UP IS DELICIOUSNESS,
RIGHT?
>> EVERYWHERE WE GO.
I'M NOT DOING ANYTHING.
>> NO, YOU'RE ABOUT TO.
YOU'RE ABOUT TO.
>> MARIO HAS THE ROASTED RED
PEPPERS IN HERE, GARLIC,
HAZELNUTS, AND THEN, LIKE, HALF
THE GOAT CHEESE, WHICH, I THINK,
THIS IS VERY COOL BECAUSE YOU
DON'T EAT A LOT OF FLOUR OR
COW'S MILK, RIGHT?
SO, THIS IS WITH MARIO ALWAYS
THINKING OF THE LADIES.
IT'S WITH GOAT CHEESE AND EXTRA
VIRGIN OLIVE OIL, SO NO COW'S
MILK THERE, AND THEN HE'S MAKING
THE PASTA WITH, WHAT, A
GLUTEN-FREE PASTA, RIGHT?
>> A GLUTEN-FREE PASTA MADE OUT
OF CORN CHRKS , WHICH IS DELICIS
A GREAT TEXTURE.
AND WE'RE GONNA MAKE THIS CRAZY
HERB CHILI OIL.
SO I'VE TAKEN SOME FRESNOS, SOME
JALAPENOS, AND SOME SERRANOS,
AND WE'RE PUTTING IT IN OIL, AND
WE'RE GONNA PUT IN A PINCH OF
SALT AND A LITTLE BIT OF DRIED
CHILIES, AND JUST KIND OF INFUSE
THAT.
WE'RE NOT REALLY TRYING TO COOK
THEM UNTIL THEY GET BLISTERS,
BUT WE'RE TRYING TO INFUSE ALL
THAT OIL.
SO, THEN, WE TAKE IT OFF THE
HEAT LIKE THAT, ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF OIL TO KIND OF COOL IT DOWN,
AND THROW IN A BIG HANDFUL OF
HERBS LIKE THAT AND JUST TOSS IT
LIKE THAT.
>> SO WE GOT BASIL IN THERE.
WE GOT PARSLEY.
WHAT ELSE?
>> BASIL, PARSLEY, AND MINT.
BUT ANY HERBS THAT YOU CAN FIND.
EVEN THYME WOULD WORK WELL.
ROSEMARY WOULDN'T WORK SO WELL
IN THIS.
>> RIGHT.
>> YOU MAKE THAT, AND THEN YOU
CAN ACTUALLY LET IT GO TO ROOM
TEMPERATURE, AND YOU JUST SAVE
IT LIKE THIS IN THE FRIDGE OR AT
ROOM TEMPERATURE.
IT'S COMPLETELY HERMETICALLY
SEALED BY THE OIL.
IT IS DELICIOUS.
IT'S A CONDIMENT THAT MAKES
ANYTHING TASTE GOOD.
THEN YOU TAKE THIS GOAT CHEESE
PESTO THAT YOU JUST MADE UP.
>> NICELY DONE.
>> WELL DONE, KaDEE.
>> WE WOULD ALSO PUT THAT IN A
JAR AND JUST COVER IT WITH A
LITTLE BIT OF EXTRA VIRGIN OLIVE
OIL, AND YOU CAN LEAVE IT IN THE
FRIDGE FOR A COUPLE OF WEEKS --
NO PROBLEM.
WE TAKE OUR CORN PASTA.
WE DUMP IT INTO AGGRESSIVELY
SEASONED WATER -- THAT IS TO
SAY, A GALLON AND A HALF, 2 1/2
TABLESPOONS OF SALT, THROW IT
IN LIKE THAT, COOK IT UNTIL ONE
MINUTE SHORT OF THE PACKAGE
INSTRUCTIONS.
WHEN IT COMES OUT, WE'RE GONNA
SHOW YOU HOW TO PUT THE WHOLE
THING TOGETHER AND MAKE THE MOST
DELICIOUS PASTA, A LA
"STRICKLANDIA."
[ LAUGHTER ]
STAY WITH US.
>> Announcer: THIS FRIDAY, IT'S
OUR HUGE HOLIDAY SPECTACULAR,
WITH A VISIT TO THE RADIO CITY
ROCKETTES.
>>> PLUS, IT'S CLINTON VERSUS
OLIVIA NEWTON-JOHN IN A
CHRISTMAS KARAOKE.
YOU DON'T WANT TO MISS IT.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
cat appe,
he opened up
Jake's very private world.
At first, Jake's family
thought they saved Ziggy,
but his connection with Jake
has been a lifesaver.
For a love this strong,
his family only feeds him Iams.
Compared to other
leading brands,
it has 50% more
animal protein...
...to help keep Ziggy's body
as strong as a love
that reaches further
than anyone's words.
Iams. Keep Love Strong.
♪
SWEETIE,
WHY ARE YOU UP?
YOU'RE NOT FEELING WELL?
[ coughing ]
LET'S GO GET
SOME TRIAMINIC.
♪
[ Female Announcer ] OTHER COLD
AND COUGH MEDICINES CAN SETTLE.
TRIAMINIC
NIGHT TIME COLD & COUGH
HAS PERFECT MIX™ TECHNOLOGY...
SO THE MEDICINE IS ALWAYS
EVENLY DISTRIBUTED
TO HELP YOUR CHILD GET
THE RIGHT AMOUNT OF MEDICINE
EVERY TIME.
TO HELP THEM FEEL BETTER FAST,
TRUST IN TRIAMINIC.
♪
Get her 1/3rd carat
diamond earrings
this week only just $29.99.
And save 75 to 80% on
all Fashion Diamonds.
At Kmart.
♪ HARK HOW THE BELLS,
SWEET SILVER BELLS ♪
♪ ALL SEEM TO SAY
THROW CARE AWAY ♪
♪ FROM EVERYWHERE,
FILLING THE AIR ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
CHEX PARTY MIX.
EASY 15-MINUTE
HOMEMADE RECIPES
YOU JUST POP IN A MICROWAVE.
LIKE CARAMEL CHOCOLATE
DRIZZLES.
HAPPIER HOLIDAYS.
CHEX PARTY MIX.
AND WE GOT ONESIES.
SOMETIMES MIRACLES
GET MESSY.
SO WE USE TIDE FREE.
NO PERFUMES OR DYES
FOR HER DELICATE SKIN.
BRAD.
NOT IT. NOT IT.
JUST KIDDING.
THAT'S OUR TIDE.
WHAT'S YOURS?
THAT'S THE GUY WHO GETS
HIS SALSA FROM NEW YORK CITY.
NEW YORK CITY?
[ alarm chirps ]
[ Male Announcer ]
'ROUND HERE, THERE'S ONLY
ONE WORD FOR SALSA: PACE.
MADE THE RIGHT WAY
FOR THAT BIG BOLD KICK.
GRAB THE SOUTHWEST
BY THE BOTTLE.
♪
I MUST HAVE
THE WRONG HOUSE.
SISTER?
WE MISSED YOU.
THEY WAITED UP ALL NIGHT
FOR YOU, YOU KNOW.
IT'S A LONG WAY
FROM WEST AFRICA.
AHH...COFFEE.
[ inhales deeply ]
HE'S HERE.
I BROUGHT YOU SOMETHING.
[ chuckles ]
REALLY?
♪
[ chuckles ]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
YOU'RE MY PRESENT
THIS YEAR.
♪ THE BEST PART OF WAKIN' UP
♪ IS FOLGERS IN YOUR CUP
[ sneezes ]
[ sniffles ]
[ Female Announcer ]
FOR EVERYTHING YOUR FACE
HAS TO FACE.
FACE IT
WITH PUFFS FACIAL TISSUES.
PUFFS HAS AIR-FLUFFED PILLOWS
FOR 40% MORE CUSHIONY
THICKNESS.
FACE EVERY DAY
WITH PUFFS SOFTNESS.
[ Female Announcer ] LET
BETTY CROCKER DO THE MEASURING
AND GET A HEAD START
ON DELICIOUS HOMEMADE COOKIES.
♪
JUST POUR, MIX...LOVE.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>>> HEY, EVERYBODY, WELCOME BACK
TO "THE CHEW'S" COZY CHRISTMAS.
TODAY WE'RE GETTING COZY WITH
THE STAR OF ABC'S
"PRIVATE PRACTICE," ONE OF OUR
FAVORITE GUESTS THAT WE'VE EVER
HAD ON THE SHOW,
KaDEE STRICKLAND.
HAD HER BACK FROM DAY ONE.
WE LOVE HER.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
MARIO'S PUTTING THE FINISHING
TOUCHES ON HIS GOAT-CHEESE
PASTA.
M.B., WHAT DO YOU GOT ROLLING
OVER THERE?
>> ALL RIGHT, SO I TAKE THE
PASTA.
I PUT IT IN A BOWL.
IT NEVER GOES IN A PAN.
I TAKE ABOUT A HALF A LADLE OF
THE PASTA WATER, THROW IT AROUND
LIKE THAT, AND THEN THROW THIS
MAGNIFICENT GLUTEN-FREE PASTA
IN, AND TOSS IT JUST LIKE A
SALAD -- THAT IS TO SAY, JUST
LIKE SO.
NOW, THE OIL'S OVER HERE
BUBBLING AWAY.
IT'S DOING WHAT I'M HOPING IT
COULD DO, WHICH IS JUST KIND OF
SIT THERE AND STEEP.
AND, THEN, TO TAKE IT TO THE
TABLE.
CAREFUL, NOW.
THE BOWL'S A LITTLE WARM.
YOU GO LIKE SO --
LIKE THAT.
IT'S KIND OF SMELLING LIKE WE'RE
DANCING, BARELY CLOTHED, IN
PIAMONTE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> I WISH YOU'D PUT ON MORE
CLOTHES IMMEDIATELY, BATALI.
JUST SAYING.
>> I DIDN'T ASK TO JOIN YOUR
DREAM, SYMON.
I JUST HAPPENED TO WALK IN
THERE.
AND THEN YOU TAKE THE HOT CHILI
OIL THAT'S AN EXCELLENT
CONDIMENT ON ANY LEVEL TO
ANYBODY ANYTIME AND GO LIKE
THAT.
AND THEN IF YOU'RE REALLY
FEELING IT, A LITTLE PURE
SHEEP'S MILK CHEESE PECORINO --
BANG, BANG, BANG.
>> OH, THAT'S GORGEOUS.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> WOW, WOW.
>> AND, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
>> OH, MY GOD.
>> SO, RIGHT AS YOU'RE GETTING
READY TO DIG INTO THAT,
CHARLOTTE HAS A BIG THING
HAPPENING TONIGHT ON
"PRIVATE PRACTICE."
COULD YOU DIVULGE ANYTHING?
>> I CAN DIVULGE THAT A COUPLE
THINGS HAPPEN.
I'M ON BED REST AND GOING MENTAL
FROM MY TRIPLETS' PREGNANCY
GOING ON.
>> THAT WOULD DO IT TO MOST
PEOPLE.
>> YES.
>> AND I AM IN THE TRENDELENBURG
POSITION AT THE START OF THE
SHOW, WHICH MEANS MY HEAD WAS ON
AN ANGLE LIKE THIS, WHICH MADE
FOR A VERY INTERESTING TAPING.
I'VE GOT TO DIG IN, AND IF I GET
GREEN TEETH, THEN IT'S ALL
RIGHT.
IT HAPPENS OCCASIONALLY, PEOPLE.
AND, THEN, OF COURSE,
SHONDA RHIMES, BEING
SHONDA RHIMES AND REALLY JUST
OPENING UP THE WORLD OF THE
CHARACTER IN ALL THOSE
INTERESTING WAYS THAT WE NEVER
ANTICIPATE AS ACTORS WHEN WE
SIGN UP TO DO A SHOW, I LEARNED
SEVEN DIFFERENT DANCE NUMBERS IN
FIVE DAYS AS PART OF MY BED-REST
FANTASY, SO YOU WILL SEE ME TURN
INTO A LITTLE BIT OF A DANCING
QUEEN, MUCH TO MY CHAGRIN.
>> I LOVE THAT.
>> THAT IS AWESOME.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> THERE'S NOTHING BETTER THAN
THAT.
>> MARIO.
>> THIS IS DELICIOUS, RIGHT?
>> HOW'S IT GOING OVER THERE,
GUYS?
>> OH, IT'S SO GOOD.
>> MMM!
>> SO GOOD.
SO, SO GOOD.
>> I LOVE TALKING WITH MY MOUTH
FULL.
NOTHING BETTER.
>> THAT'S OUR SPECIALTY.
WE GENERALLY WAIT UNTIL YOUR
MOUTH'S FULL.
THEN WE ALL WINK AT EACH OTHER
LIKE THIS AND SAY --
>> OH, MY GOD, MARIO.
BLESS YOUR HEART.
I FEEL LIKE I'M BACK IN ITALY,
JUST LIKE A GIRL SHOULD.
>> YEP.
ABSOLUTELY.
>> I HATE TO BRING UP SOMETHING
THAT MIGHT BE POTENTIALLY SAD
FOR YOU, BUT THIS IS THE LAST
SEASON OF "PRIVATE PRACTICE,"
CORRECT?
[ AUDIENCE AWE -- AWs ]
WHAT'S UP FOR YOU NEXT?
>> THE WORLD IS MY OYSTER IN
TERMS OF BEING OPEN AND
AVAILABLE, AND SO FAR -- I'M
GONNA TALK TO YOU LIKE THIS,
LIKE I'M MYSTERIOUS.
SO FAR THINGS LOOK PRETTY BRIGHT
IN MY FUTURE.
>> NICE!
>> TRUST ME, YOU'LL KNOW ABOUT
IT.
YOU'LL KNOW ABOUT IT.
>> YOU WILL LAND ON SOMETHING
AMAZING.
I'M SURE ABOUT IT, YES.
>> I'M JUST GONNA COME BACK HERE
WEEKLY.
NO PROBLEM.
>> WE'D BE GLAD TO HAVE YOU.
>> ALL RIGHT, THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR JOINING US TODAY, KaDEE.
WATCH "PRIVATE PRACTICE" TUESDAY
NIGHTS AT 10:00 P.M. RIGHT HERE
ON ABC.
COMING UP NEXT, MY ORNAMENT
WORKSHOP.
>> Announcer: UP NEXT, CLINTON'S
WORKSHOP HAS LAST-MINUTE DECOR
TIPS THAT CAN TAKE YOUR
ALREADY-DECKED-OUT TREE TO THE
NEXT LEVEL.
STAY TUNED.
LOTS OF DIFFERENT WAYSer E
TO SAY GET WELL
TO YOUR LOVED ONES.
♪
THIS CAME FOR YOU, MOMMY.
[ Female Announcer ]
BUT IT TAKES THE TOUCH
OF KLEENEX® BRAND,
AMERICA'S SOFTEST TISSUE,
TO TURN A GESTURE
INTO A COMPLETE GIFT OF CARE.
[ barks ]
SEND YOUR OWN FREE
KLEENEX® CARE PACK...
FULL OF SOOTHING ESSENTIALS
AT KLEENEX.COM.
KLEENEX®.
AMERICA'S SOFTEST TISSUE.
♪
MANY HOT DOGS
ARE WITHIN YOU.
TRY PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO,
IT'S THE POWER OF PEPTO,
BUT IT FITS IN YOUR POCKET.
NOW TELL THE WORLD
DANIEL...
OF PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO.
♪ BUT THE FIRE IS
SO DELIGHTFUL ♪
NOTHING MELTS AWAY THE COLD
LIKE A HOT, DELICIOUS BOWL
OF CHICKEN NOODLE SOUP
FROM CAMPBELL'S.
♪ LET IT SNOW, LET IT SNOW
ONE SQUARE INCH OF
DELICIOUSLY SMOOTH CHOCOLATE
IN CREAMY MILK...
OR RICH DARK.
INCREDIBLE INDULGENCE.
ONE SQUARE INCH OF BLISS.
HERSHEY'S BLISS.
>> Announcer: "THE CHEW" WILL
CONTINUE IN A MOMENT, HERE ON
!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>>> WELCOME BACK TO "THE CHEW'S"
COZY CHRISTMAS.
THERE IS NOTHING COZIER THAN
ENJOYING A NICE GLASS OF WINE --
OR THREE -- NEXT TO THE
CHRISTMAS TREE.
BUT INSTEAD OF DECORATING THE
SAME OLD BORING ORNAMENTS YOU'VE
HAD FOR YEARS, MAYBE IT'S TIME
TO TAKE THAT TREE FROM DRAB TO
FAB.
THAT'S RIGHT.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> IT'S TIME FOR --
♪ CLINTON'S WORKSHOP
>> All: WE'RE ELVES!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> YAY!
>> I'LL BE YOUR ELF ANY DAY,
CLINTON.
>> THANK YOU, SWEETHEART.
ALL RIGHT, YOUR WHOLE FAMILY'S
GOING TO LOVE MAKING THESE
ADORABLE LIGHT-BULB SNOWMEN, AND
YOU PROBABLY HAVE HALF OF THIS
STUFF ALREADY LYING AROUND YOUR
HOUSE.
HOW CUTE IS THAT LITTLE THING?
>> SO CUTE!
>> ALL RIGHT, SO, THE FIRST
THING YOU WANT TO DO IS START
WITH A LIGHTBULB, ALL RIGHT?
SO THE MORE OPAQUE THE LIGHTBULB
IS, THE BETTER.
SO, LIKE, AN EXTRA SOFT WHITE IS
A GOOD CHOICE.
AND YOU CAN EVEN USE A LIGHTBULB
THAT HAS BLOWN OUT IN YOUR
HOUSE, SO IT'S FREE.
RATHER THAN THROW IT IN THE
GARBAGE, YOU CAN USE IT TO MAKE
AN ORNAMENT.
>> I CAN'T EVEN GET THE GLOVES
ON, FOR CRYING OUT LOUD.
I'M GONNA FOREGO THE GLOVES.
THEN WHAT YOU WANT TO DO IS TAKE
SOME SPRAY ADHESIVE, YOU KNOW,
MY FAVORITE ITEM.
[ LAUGHTER ]
YOU CAN WEAR THEM, THOUGH.
>> I'M FOLLOWING DIRECTIONS
EXACTLY TODAY.
>> THANK YOU.
I APPRECIATE THAT FOR A CHANGE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> I'M PRETTY SURE IT'S
CLINTON'S WORKSHOP, RIGHT?
>> ALL RIGHT, SO YOU'RE GONNA
SPRAY THE ENTIRE BULB LIGHTLY
WITH LIGHT BURSTS OF SPRAY
ADHESIVE.
I LOVE ME SOME SPRAY ADHESIVE.
>> SO DOES SYMON.
>> ALL RIGHT, GOOD.
AND WHEN YOU HAVE A NICE, LIGHT
COAT, WHILE IT'S STILL TACKY,
WHAT YOU WANT TO DO IS START
PUTTING YOUR GLITTER ON IT, ALL
RIGHT?
SO, YOU'RE USING GLITTER.
A FINE GLITTER IS GOING TO WORK
BEST, RIGHT?
SOMETHING THAT'S A LITTLE
IRIDESCENT IS ALSO VERY NICE.
THIS HAS LITTLE FLECKS OF PINK
AND RED IN THERE.
OKAY, AND YOU'RE GOING UNTIL YOU
COVER THE ENTIRE THING.
>> AH!
SO BEAUTIFUL.
>> SO BEAUTIFUL, RIGHT?
OKAY.
ONCE YOU'VE GOT THAT ALL
COVERED, YOU'RE GONNA SET THAT
SOMEWHERE AND LET IT DRY.
ALL RIGHT, AND I'VE GOT ONES FOR
YOU THAT ARE ALREADY DRIED,
OKAY?
>> THAT IS SO BEAUTIFUL.
>> THEN, ONCE THEY'RE DRIED, YOU
WANT TO PAINT THE TOP, YOU KNOW,
THE SOCKET PART -- THE PLUG, I
GUESS YOU COULD CALL IT.
YOU PAINT THAT BLACK, SO IT'LL
BE THE SNOWMAN'S HAT.
YOU COULD USE NAIL POLISH IF YOU
WANTED TO OR ANY PAINT.
AND THEN YOU WANT TO TIE A
LITTLE BIT OF BLACK STRING
AROUND THE BASE TO HANG THE
ORNAMENT AT THIS PARTICULAR
TIME.
ALL RIGHT, SO, NOW IT'S TIME TO
DECORATE, AND ALL YOU NEED IS
THIS CRAFT PAINT.
THEY CALL IT PUFF PAINT OR PUFFY
PAINT.
IT COMES IN A LITTLE APPLICATOR
LIKE THIS.
IT GIVES YOU A NICE, FINE TIP.
OKAY, SO, WHAT YOU WANT TO DO
IS, CREATE -- WHY DON'T WE DO
THE NOSES FIRST?
LET'S TAKE OUR ORANGE, ALL
RIGHT?
SO WE'RE GONNA DO A CARROT NOSE.
SO, AT THE TOP OF THE SNOWMAN,
SORT OF IN THIS GENERAL AREA,
THIS IS THE HEAD OVER HERE.
>> RIGHT.
>> THAT'S WHERE YOU WANT TO PUT
YOUR NOSE, IN THIS GENERAL AREA.
SO WE DO A CARROT SORT OF FACING
OFF TO EITHER SIDE, SO WE DO A
LITTLE TRIANGLE FOR THE NOSE.
ALL RIGHT.
TRIANGLE FOR THE NOSE.
OKAY, HOW Y'ALL DOING?
>> I'M DONE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> OKAY.
YEAH, MINE'S LIKE A POINT, YEAH.
GO AHEAD.
>> LIKE THIS?
>> YEAH, MICHAEL'S IS BIGGER.
THAT'S GOOD.
DAPHNE'S IS PERFECT.
>> HOW ARE YOU DOING, MARIO?
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> ALSO VERY NICE.
YOURS IS POINTING DOWNWARD,
OKAY, GOOD.
ALL RIGHT.
NOW YOU WANT TO USE THE BLACK
DOTS.
NOW, YOU WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT
YOU SHAKE THIS UP, AND WE'RE
GOING TO CREATE A COUPLE OF
EYES.
SO, OVER THE CARROT, WE'RE GOING
TO MAKE AN EYE.
AND THIS IS WHAT I DO TO PUT THE
PAINT.
YOU PUT IT DOWN, PUT IT ON THE
LIGHT BULB, GIVE IT A GENTLE
SQUEEZE, AND THEN LIFT IT UP.
>> DROP IT LIKE IT'S HOT.
>> YES.
GENTLE SQUEEZE, AND THEN PULL
UP.
AND WE'RE ALSO GOING TO DO THE
SAME THING.
WE'RE GOING TO PRETEND THAT IT'S
LITTLE CHARCOAL DOTS FOR THE
MOUTH, SO WE'RE GOING TO MAKE A
SMILE OF CHARCOAL DOTS UNDER THE
MOUTH, RIGHT?
SO HE'S A HAPPY SNOWMAN.
DOT AND UP, AND DOT AND UP.
WHOOPS.
>> WHOO.
OH.
>> OKAY, AND DOT AND UP.
HOW YOU DOING?
>> I LOVE THIS.
>> GOOD, CLINTON.
THE ONLY PROBLEM IS, USUALLY
WHEN MEN ARE COVERED IN
SPARKLES, IT DOESN'T MEAN THAT
THEY WERE CRAFTING.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> OH, YES.
THAT'S TRUE.
IT MEANS YOU WERE AT THE CLUB.
>> OH, WHEE!
>> OKAY.
AND, OH, MARIO HAS AN OPEN MOUTH
ON HIS.
LOOK AT THAT.
AND THEN -- ALL RIGHT, I'M
RUNNING OUT OF TIME.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
BUT NOW TAKE YOUR HOT GLUE GUNS,
OKAY?
PUT YOUR SNOWMEN DOWN JUST FOR A
SECOND.
TAKE YOUR HOT GLUE GUNS, PUT A
DOT OF GLUE ON A LITTLE BRANCH.
PUT A DOT OF GLUE ON THE BRANCH.
I RAN OVER.
OKAY.
AND THEN YOU HOLD IT ONTO THE
SNOWMAN'S SIDE LIKE THIS FOR AN
ARM, AND YOU LET THAT DRY.
AND WHEN WE COME BACK, I'M GONNA
SHOW YOU HOW FROSTY TURNED OUT.
PLUS, WE'RE GONNA MAKE CUPCAKE
ORNAMENTS.
THEY'RE AWESOME.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Announcer: STILL TO COME,
BECAUSE THEY'RE GOING TO GO
STRAIGHT FOR THE GIFTS ON
CHRISTMAS MORNING, DAPHNE'S GOT
A BREAKFAST TREAT YOU CAN EAT BY
THE TREE.
STAY TUNED.
UE BREWER?
OH, IT'S GREAT!
NOW I CAN BREW MY COFFEE
JUST THE WAY I LOVE IT.
HOW DO YOU DO THAT?
WELL, INSIDE THE BREWER,
THERE'S THIS TRAIN
THAT'S POWERFUL ENOUGH
TO CARRY MORE COFFEE
AND FRESH WATER TO MAKE COFFEE
THAT'S STRONGER
AND BIGGER...
AND EVEN HOTTER!
ACTUALLY, I JUST PRESS
THIS BUTTON.
BREW THE COFFEE YOU LOVE --
STRONGER, BIGGER, OR HOTTER --
WITH THE KEURIG VUE.
♪
Get her 1/3rd carat
diamond earrings
this week only just $29.99.
And save 75 to 80% on
all Fashion Diamonds.
At Kmart.
SURE, BISQUICK MAKES
DELICIOUS PANCAKES,
BUT THAT'S JUST THE START.
UNLEASH THE HIDDEN POWER
OF BISQUICK.
SEE WHAT YOU CAN MAKE
AT BISQUICK.COM.
BODY WASHES WITH PAPER
THAT REACTS LIKE SKIN.
IF OTHERS CAN STRIP THIS PAPER,
IMAGINE HOW HARSH
THEY CAN BE TO YOUR SKIN.
OH MY GOSH.
[ Female Announcer ]
Dove IS DIFFERENT.
ITS NEW BREAKTHROUGH FORMULA
CHANGES EVERYTHING.
NEW Dove.
THIS IS CARE.
WE DON'T LET FREQUENT HEARTBURN
COME BETWEEN US
AND WHAT WE LOVE.
SO IF YOU'RE ONE OF THEM PEOPLE
WHO GETS HEARTBURN
AND THEN TREATS DAY AFTER DAY...
BLOCK THE ACID WITH PRILOSEC OTC
AND DON'T GET HEARTBURN
IN THE FIRST PLACE!
[ Male Announcer ]
ONE PILL EACH MORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBURN.
AND DON'T GET HEARTBURN
IN THE FIRST PLACE!
Balsamic, Vinegar and Oil,
Authentic Italian Herbs.
Just a few of the
ingredients you'll find in
Hidden Valley's Italians
and Vinaigrettes.
You know Hidden Valley for our
Ranch, but you've never
tasted anything like this.
We were going through so much
of the bargain detergent.
And the clothes
didn't look as good.
But since we switched to Tide
we use much less.
An amazing clean
for all three
of our full-grown
dependent bundles of joy.
That's my Tide,
what's yours?
♪ I WOKE UP TO A FEELING
♪ EVERY LITTLE THING
HAS MEANING ♪
♪ I WOKE UP TO A LIGHT BULB ON
♪ EVERY LITTLE THING
IS POSSIBLE NOW ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
WE'VE ADDED A TOUCH OF
PHILADELPHIA CREAM CHEESE
TO OUR KRAFT NATURAL CHEESE
TO MAKE IT CREAMIER
SO WHATEVER YOU MAKE
ISN'T JUST GOOD, IT'S AMAZING.
♪ ...IS AMAZING
WITH THE LOVE THAT I FOUND ♪
♪
>> Announcer: LOOKING FOR THE
PERFECT GIFT?
GO TO THECHEW.COM WEBSTORE.
SEE OUR HOLIDAY GIFT GUIDE AND
CHEW-SENTIALS FOR GREAT DEALS ON
FABULOUS MERCHANDISE.
"THE CHEW" WEBSTORE -- YOU ARE
ONE CLICK AWAY.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>>> WELCOME BACK TO "THE CHEW."
"CLINTON'S WORKSHOP" IS IN FULL
SWING.
IF MY LIGHTBULB SNOWMEN WEREN'T
CUTE ENOUGH, LOOK AT THIS.
WE ALL DID OUR OWN SNOWMEN.
THEY ALL CAME OUT GREAT.
THAT WAS IN A MATTER OF A FEW
MINUTES.
BUT I'M ABOUT TO SHOW YOU GUYS
SOMETHING EVEN SWEETER.
THESE ARE CUPCAKE ORNAMENTS THAT
LOOK GOOD ENOUGH TO EAT, AND
THEY'RE SUPER-SIMPLE TO MAKE.
LOOK AT THAT -- ADORABLE.
START WITH A BALL ORNAMENT.
BEFORE I SAY THAT, I JUST WANT
TO MAKE SURE EVERYBODY KNOWS --
YOU CAN NEVER USE THESE LIGHT
BULBS AGAIN.
I JUST WANT TO SAY THAT -- DON'T
TRY PLUGGING THIS IN TO A
SOCKET.
OKAY, ALL RIGHT.
JUST HAD TO SAY THAT.
ALL RIGHT.
THE FIRST THING YOU WANT TO DO
IS START WITH A BALL ORNAMENT.
SO ANY OPAQUE COLOR WORKS.
I'M GONNA USE AN ORNAMENT HERE
THAT'S GOT, LIKE, A PEARL
FINISH.
>> OH, MY GOSH.
>> AND NOW TO APPLY THE
FROSTING, WHAT YOU DO IS, YOU
TAKE YOUR GLUE.
IT'S THIS WHITE GLUE.
AND YOU JUST START POURING IT
ON.
YOU WANT TO DO A VERY LIGHT LINE
ABOUT HALFWAY DOWN THE BALL,
OKAY?
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF GLUE ABOUT
HALFWAY DOWN THE BALL.
AND THEN ON THE TOP OF THE BALL,
YOU CAN GO A LITTLE BIT HEAVIER
WITH YOUR APPLICATION.
THE OTHER THING YOU COULD DO IF
YOU WANTED TO COLOR THIS IS ADD
SOME FOOD DYE TO YOUR WHITE GLUE
AND MIX THAT UP.
I'M ACTUALLY GONNA DO THAT ON
THIS ONE.
SO YOU GUYS CAN DO THE WHITE.
I'LL DO A LITTLE BIT OF COLOR
HERE.
AND I'M JUST GONNA PAINT THIS ON
VERY QUICKLY.
ALL RIGHT.
SO YOU COVER THE TOP HALF OF THE
ORNAMENT WITH GLUE.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE
SUPER-CAREFUL ABOUT THIS.
YOU WANT IT TO LOOK LIKE ICING,
THE WAY YOU WOULD ICE A CUPCAKE.
SOME PEOPLE LIKE THAT VERY
PRECISE.
SOME DON'T.
SO IT'S UP TO YOU.
AND THEN -- YOU GUYS GOOD?
>> YES.
>> OKAY.
THEN YOU WANT TO TAKE YOUR
GLITTER.
>> OKAY, GLUE?
>> GLUE, YEAH.
YOU WANT A LITTLE BIT MORE GLUE
THAN THAT.
SO, YOU CAN USE YOUR FOAM BRUSH
TO MOVE THAT AROUND A LITTLE
BIT.
THEN WHAT YOU WANT TO DO IS TAKE
SOME GLITTER.
NOW, YOU CAN USE CHUNKY GLITTER
TO ADD A LITTLE BIT OF --
DIMENSION.
>> CHUNKY!
CHUNKY GLITTER!
I LIKE THEM CHUNKY.
>> NOW, KEEP IN MIND THAT
YOUR --
[ LAUGHTER ]
THAT'S A WHITE.
THE WHITE GLUE IS GOING TO DRY
CLEAR, JUST SO YOU KNOW, ALL
RIGHT?
>> UH-OH.
>> AND THEN WE DO THAT.
HOW ARE WE DOING?
GOOD.
MICHAEL, YOU'RE DOING
FABULOUSLY.
>> I GOT A HAIR IN MINE, AND I
KNOW IT WASN'T MINE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> YOUR EYEBROWS ARE --
>> ALL RIGHT, GUYS.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S MOVE ALONG TO
THE NEXT STEP, OKAY?
WE ONLY HAVE A COUPLE OF MINUTES
LEFT.
THEN YOU WANT TO TAKE A CUPCAKE
WRAPPER, TYPICAL CUPCAKE
WRAPPER, AND YOU WANT TO
HOT-GLUE A DOLLOP OF GLUE --
WHOOPS.
I LOST MY GLUE.
PUT A DOLLOP OF GLUE ON THE
BOTTOM OF THE INSIDE OF YOUR
CUPCAKE WRAPPER, ALL RIGHT?
AND THEN YOU WANT TO PUT YOUR
ORNAMENT IN ON A SLIGHT ANGLE.
>> A JAUNTY ANGLE, WOULD IT BE?
>> A JAUNTY, JAUNTY ANGLE WOULD
BE NICE.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA LET THAT
SET.
>> IT'S SO CUTE!
>> THEN YOU CAN TAKE A BEAD.
THEY HAVE BEADS THAT LOOK LIKE
LITTLE CHERRIES.
WE'RE GONNA PUT A CHERRY ON TOP,
ALSO USING A LITTLE BIT OF HOT
GLUE.
[ GROWLS ]
I'M GONNA BORROW YOUR GUN.
>> YES, PLEASE.
>> MY GLUE STICK FELL OUT.
SO I THINK IT'S MUCH MORE
FESTIVE, WHEN YOU'RE GLUING TWO
ROUND THINGS TOGETHER, YOU PUT A
LITTLE DOLLOP ON ONE AND THEN
YOU PUT A LITTLE DOLLOP OF THE
HOT GLUE ON THE OTHER.
AND SO THAT JOINS THE TWO ROUND
PIECES TOGETHER NICELY.
ALL RIGHT, HOLD ON.
PUT THAT ON TOP LIKE THAT.
AND THEN YOU HAVE A CUPCAKE WITH
A CHERRY ON TOP.
>> OH, MY GOSH!
THAT'S AMAZING.
>> AND YOU CAN TIE A LITTLE
RIBBON AND HANG IT FROM THE
TREE, AND YOU ARE GOOD TO GO.
>> OH, CUTE.
>> VOILA!
SURE TO SATISFY YOUR SWEET
TOOTH.
NOW, ANOTHER THING.
"CLINTON'S WORKSHOP" IS CLOSING
ITS DOORS FOR THE SEASON.
BUT I HAD TO SHOW YOU ONE -- OH,
I KNOW -- ONE FINAL CRAFT THAT
I'M SLIGHTLY OBSESSED WITH.
IT'S THE PEANUT REINDEER.
HERE IT IS.
OKAY, I'LL SHOW YOU RIGHT NOW.
OKAY.
>> OH!
>> OH, MY GOD.
ALL YOU NEED IS A PEANUT.
YOU USE A LITTLE BLACK MARKER
FOR THE EYES, THE NOSE IS THE
TIP OF A STRAIGHT PIN, AND THE
EARS ARE PIPE CLEANERS, AND THE
ANTLERS ARE THIN, LITTLE WIRE.
AND YOU CAN HANG IT WITH A SMALL
EYE HOOK AND STRING.
HOW ADORABLE IS THAT?
>> ADORABLE.
>> LOOK AT THAT.
THESE ARE ALL THINGS THAT YOU
CAN DO TODAY TO MAKE YOUR TREE
FREAKING AWESOME!
>> I LOVE THAT!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> OH, MY GOD, THAT IS SO CUTE!
>> ALL RIGHT, COMING UP NEXT,
DAPHNE'S GONNA MAKE A CHRISTMAS
MORNING MUFFIN THAT IS
DELICIOUS.
DON'T GO AWAY.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Announcer: THIS HOLIDAY
SEASON, ORDER YOUR COPY OF "THE
CHEW -- FOOD. LIFE. FUN." BOOK.
OVER A HUNDRED MOUTHWATERING
RECIPES AND TONS OF FABULOUS
ENTERTAINING TIPS -- EVERYTHING
YOU NEED TO MAKE YOUR HOLIDAYS
PERFECT.
IT'S ALSO A FANTASTIC GIFT OR
STOCKING STUFFER, AVAILABLE ON
THECHEW.COM OR WHEREVER BOOKS
ARE SOLD.
MAKE EVERY DAY A HOLIDAY PARTY
IN YOUR KITCHEN.
LOSEC OTC WILDBY
IS THE SAME FREQUENT HEARTBURN
TREATMENT AS PRILOSEC OTC.
NOW WITH A FANCY COATING
THAT GIVES YOU A BURST
OF WILDBERRY FLAVOR.
NOW WHY MAKE A FLAVORED
HEARTBURN PILL?
BECAUSE THIS IS AMERICA.
AND WE DON'T JUST
MAKE THINGS YOU WANT,
WE MAKE THINGS YOU
DIDN'T EVEN KNOW YOU WANTED.
LIKE A SPOON FORK.
SPRAY CHEESE.
AND JEANS MADE
OUT OF SWEATPANTS.
SO GRAB YOURSELF SOME
NEW PRILOSEC OTC WILDBERRY.
[ Male Announcer ]
ONE PILL EACH MORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBURN.
SATISFACTION GUARANTEED
OR YOUR MONEY BACK.
Challenge that with new Olay
Facial Hair Removal Duo.
A two-step process that removes
even coarse, stubborn
facial hair gently.
Plenty of gain,
without all that pain...
With Olay.
ONE SQUARE INCH OF
DELICIOUSLY SMOOTH CHOCOLATE
IN CREAMY MILK...
OR RICH DARK.
INCREDIBLE INDULGENCE.
ONE SQUARE INCH OF BLISS.
HERSHEY'S BLISS.
[ Female Announcer ]
ONE DROP OF ULTRA DAWN
HAS TWICE THE EVERYDAY
GREASE CLEANING INGREDIENTS
OF ONE DROP OF THE LEADING
NON-CONCENTRATED BRAND...
TO CLEAN 2X MORE GREASY DISHES.
DAWN DOES MORE.
SO IT'S NOT A CHORE.
Here's a better idea.
Pillsbury Grands!
Flaky Layers Biscuits
In just 15 minutes
the light delicate layers
add a layer of warmth
to your next dinner.
Pillsbury Grands Biscuits
Let the making begin.
TVO: Tina's just trieds
Garnier Nutrisse
TINA: With avocado,
olive and shea.
It's actually nourishing
while it colors...
Richer? Check.
More radiant? Yes!
Nourished hair,
better color.
You better believe it.
Garnier Nutrisse.
it sparks a movement.
Because people can't
keep it to themselves.
Look !
No ugly spots !
Awesome!
Incredible shine.
I'm switching for good.
Love, love, love Finish!
Over a million people
have switched to Finish.
Visit us on Facebook.
SO YOU THINK
SANTA WILL LIKE THESE...
RED AND GREEN M&M'S?
I DON'T KNOW!
I NEVER MET THE GUY!
WHAAAAA!
HE DOES EXIST!
THEY DO EXIST!
UHM... SANTA?
>> Announcer: WELCOME BACK TO
"THE CHEW'S" COZY CHRISTMAS.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> WELCOME BACK TO "THE CHEW."
THERE IS NOTHING I LOVE MORE
THAN WAKING UP ON A SNOWY
CHRISTMAS MORNING, GIVING
PRESENTS, AND SHARING A
DELICIOUS BREAKFAST WITH MY
FAMILY.
SO I'M ABOUT TO SHOW YOU AN
IRRESISTIBLE APPLE-CINNAMON
MUFFIN THAT YOU CAN MAKE AND
WILL MAKE YOUR ENTIRE HOUSE
SMELL COZY ON CHRISTMAS MORNING.
CARLA AND I ARE GONNA DO IT
TOGETHER.
IT'S A REALLY GOOD RECIPE.
KIND OF, FOR ME, THE START OF A
COZY CHRISTMAS IS WE ALL PILE
DOWN -- MY MOM IS 1 OF 6, SO WE
HAVE, LIKE, 25 PEOPLE AT OUR
HOUSE.
WE ALL RUN DOWN IN THE MORNING,
AND THE KIDS GET TO OPEN THEIR
STOCKINGS FIRST.
BUT BEFORE YOU DO THAT, YOU KIND
OF WANT TO GIVE THEM A LITTLE
SOMETHING TO HAVE IN THEIR
HANDS.
THIS IS A RECIPE YOU CAN MAKE
AHEAD OF TIME, PUT IN YOUR
FREEZER, POP IN THE OVEN, AND
HAVE IT READY SO YOU'RE NOT
WORKING ALL MORNING LONG.
>> BUT THESE ARE TWO OF MY
FAVORITE FLAVORS, CINNAMON AND
APPLE.
LOVE IT.
>> OH, THEY'RE DELICIOUS.
AND, OF COURSE, YOU GUYS KNOW
IT'S ME, SO THIS RECIPE IS A
LITTLE BIT HEALTHIER THAN YOUR
NORMAL ONE.
IT COMES IN ABOUT 200 CALORIES
LESS THAN YOUR TYPICAL APPLE
MUFFIN, SO YOU CAN ACTUALLY
REALLY ENJOY THE HOLIDAYS AND
KIND OF LOOK FORWARD TO, YOU
KNOW, GETTING BACK ON TRACK.
PLUS, I KNOW THAT CHRISTMAS
EATING KIND OF STARTS LATER IN
THE DAY, AND YOU MAYBE WANT TO
START THE MORNING WITH A LITTLE
BIT OF A HEALTHY PUNCH.
>> YEAH.
>> SO HERE'S WHAT WE DID.
WE TOOK TWO CUPS OF OATMEAL.
THESE ARE JUST SORT OF
QUICK-COOKING, ROLLED OATS.
DIVIDE THEM IN HALF, AND YOU'RE
GONNA PULSE ONE CUP IN THE FOOD
PROCESSOR TO MAKE KIND OF AN OAT
FLOUR CONSISTENCY.
SO WE TOOK THAT.
WE TOOK A CUP OF ALL-PURPOSE
FLOUR, AND WE TOOK HALF A CUP OF
BROWN SUGAR.
THAT'S THE ONLY SUGAR GOING IN
THIS RECIPE, 'CAUSE THE
SWEETNESS IS ACTUALLY COMING
FROM THE APPLES.
SO WE WHISK ALL THE INGREDIENTS
TOGETHER.
A LITTLE PINCH OF
SALT, AND THEN I TOOK A GALA
APPLE, OR YOU COULD USE LIKE A
PINK LADY -- ANY KIND OF SWEET
APPLE.
PUT IT INTO A SMALL DICE.
AND HERE I HAVE TWO TABLESPOONS
OF BUTTER THAT I LET BROWN,
WHICH JUST MEANS YOU LET THE
MILK SOLIDS CARAMELIZE SO THEY
ADD THAT EVEN NUTTIER, RICHER
TASTE TO THE APPLES WHEN YOU PUT
THEM IN TO SAUTE.
>> SO, YOU LEFT THE SKINS ON
BECAUSE OF THE FIBER AND ALSO
BECAUSE OF THE COLOR?
>> I DID.
ALSO, THE COLOR, BUT I ALSO WANT
IT TO HOLD ITS CONSISTENCY,
BECAUSE HERE'S THE DEAL -- WHEN
IT GOES INTO THE MUFFIN, IT'S
GOING COOK DOWN, BUT I KIND OF
WANT IT TO STILL HAVE A LITTLE
BIT OF A BITE.
YOU GUYS ARE ALREADY CHOWING.
WHAT'S GOING ON OVER HERE?
>> THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
>> ALL I NEED IS A HOT BUTTERED
RUM, BABY!
COME ON!
>> I WAS SO HAPPY WHEN YOU SAID
THEY'RE A THIRD OF THE CALORIES,
'CAUSE I'VE HAD THREE ALREADY.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> SO THERE YOU GO.
ONE BEATEN EGG.
HERE'S HOW I MAKE THE BUTTER --
ONE BEATEN EGG, A CUP OF
BUTTERMILK.
THAT'S WHAT'S KEEPING THEM
REALLY MOIST OVER THERE.
I ALREADY DID MY SALT.
A LITTLE BIT OF CINNAMON TO GET
THAT APPLE-PIE FLAVOR.
A LITTLE BIT OF NUTMEG, AGAIN,
FOR THE APPLE-PIE FLAVOR.
YOU CAN ALSO FILE YOUR NAILS
WHILE YOU'RE DOING THIS.
AND THEN, ONCE THAT BATTER COMES
TOGETHER, YOU JUST FOLD IN YOUR
APPLES.
AND CARLA IS PUTTING THE
EXTRA-SPECIAL HOLIDAY TOUCH ON
THEM FOR ME.
THIS IS A STREUSEL TOPPING.
IT'S JUST YOUR ROLLED OATS
AGAIN, YOUR FLOUR, AND A LITTLE
PINCH OF ANY OF THE ADDITIONAL
SPICES THAT YOU MIGHT WANT.
AND THEN HERE'S HOW WE BIND
IT -- WITH COCONUT OIL.
YOU DON'T EVEN NEED ANY BUTTER
IN THIS PORTION OF THE RECIPE,
ALTHOUGH WE DID USE IT WITH THE
APPLES.
>> I LOVE -- AND THEN THERE'S NO
SUGAR.
BECAUSE THE THING IS YOU DON'T
WANT THOSE KIDS HAVING THEIR
STOCKINGS AND HAVING -- I
KNOW -- BACKED UP ON SUGAR, AND
THEN EVERYBODY GETS DOWN.
THEY OPEN THEIR GIFTS, OTHER
PEOPLE'S GIFTS, AND EVERYTHING.
I KNOW.
>> EXACTLY.
YOU WANT TO KEEP THEM CALM IN
THE MORNING.
>> UH-HUH.
>> AND WHAT WE SERVE THEM WITH
AT OUR HOUSE IS EITHER
STRAWBERRY BUTTER, WHICH WE HAVE
THE RECIPE FOR ON THECHEW.COM
FOR YOU, OR JUST A SIMPLE APPLE
BUTTER IF YOU DON'T FEEL LIKE
PUTTING EXTRA TIME INTO MAKING
IT.
SO, AFTER YOU PUT THE STREUSEL
ON TOP, YOU GO AHEAD AND PUT IT
IN THE OVEN.
IT'S A 400-DEGREE OVEN FOR ABOUT
15 MINUTES.
REMEMBER, THESE ARE GOING TO
STAY REALLY MOIST, REALLY DENSE.
THEY'RE PERFECT HOT OUT OF THE
OVEN.
AND IF YOU WANTED TO MAKE THEM
AHEAD OF TIME, HERE'S HOW YOU DO
IT -- SCOOP THEM INTO THE MUFFIN
TIN, COVER IT TIGHTLY WITH
PLASTIC WRAP AND TINFOIL, PUT IT
IN YOUR FREEZER.
WHEN YOU WANT TO COOK THEM UP,
BRING THEM OUT OF THE OVEN AND
EITHER LEAVE THEM IN A PREHEATED
OVEN FOR TEN MINUTES TO DEFROST
OR JUST LEAVE THEM ON YOUR
COUNTER FOR AN HOUR AND THEN PUT
THEM IN THE OVEN AND BAKE IT AS
USUAL.
REALLY EASY TO MAKE AHEAD OF
TIME, ALL RIGHT?
[ APPLAUSE ]
IN THE OVEN.
>> SO GOOD.
>> DAPH, I HAVE A QUESTION FOR
YOU.
>> YEAH?
>> DOES THE BOTTOM OF THE MUFFIN
HAVE LESS CALORIES THAN THE TOP?
BECAUSE MARIO KEEPS TAKING THE
TOPS --
>> ARE YOU A TOP EATER?
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> HE TAKES THE TOPS, GIVES ME
THE BOTTOMS.
>> HE SEEMS TO LIKE THE BOTTOMS.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> YOU KNOW, EVERYONE HAS THEIR
PREFERENCE.
BUT THE GOOD NEWS FOR YOU IS
THAT YOU CAN HAVE THE TOP AND
THE BOTTOM FOR ONLY 43 CENTS A
SERVING ON THESE BABIES.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THEY'RE PACKED FULL OF FIBER,
TONS AND TONS OF DELICIOUS
FLAVOR, AND YOUR FAMILY WILL
LOVE THEM.
STICK AROUND.
MORE "CHEW" WHEN WE GET BACK.
>> THEY'RE SO GOOD.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Announcer: TOMORROW ON "THE
CHEW," WE'RE INVITING YOU TO
"THE CHEW'S" FAMILY HOLIDAY
DINNER TABLE.
>> WELCOME TO MY NEW YORK CITY
KITCHEN.
>> Announcer: AND HAS CARLA
FOUND THE LATEST TREND IN
HOLIDAY PARTY-HOPPING?
>> OH, WE'RE SO GETTING ONTO
THIS ELEVATOR.
>> Announcer: YOU'LL FIND OUT
TOMORROW ON "THE CHEW."
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
I HONESTLY LOVED SMOKING,
AND I HONESTLY DIDN'T THINK
I WOULD EVER QUIT.
[ Male Announcer ]
ALONG WITH SUPPORT,
CHANTIX IS PROVEN
TO HELP PEOPLE QUIT SMOKING.
IT REDUCES THE URGE TO SMOKE.
IT PUT ME AT EASE THAT YOU COULD
SMOKE ON THE FIRST WEEK.
[ Male Announcer ] SOME PEOPLE
HAD CHANGES IN BEHAVIOR,
THINKING OR MOOD,
HOSTILITY, AGITATION,
DEPRESSED MOOD AND SUICIDAL
THOUGHTS OR ACTIONS
WHILE TAKING
OR AFTER STOPPING CHANTIX.
IF YOU NOTICE ANY OF THESE
STOP TAKING CHANTIX AND CALL
YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ANY HISTORY OF DEPRESSION
OR OTHER
MENTAL HEALTH PROBLEMS,
WHICH COULD GET WORSE
WHILE TAKING CHANTIX.
DON'T TAKE CHANTIX IF
YOU'VE HAD A SERIOUS ALLERGIC
OR SKIN REACTION TO IT.
IF YOU DEVELOP THESE
STOP TAKING CHANTIX
AND SEE YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY
AS SOME CAN BE
LIFE-THREATENING.
IF YOU HAVE A HISTORY OF HEART
OR BLOOD VESSEL PROBLEMS,
TELL YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU HAVE
NEW OR WORSE SYMPTOMS.
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU HAVE SYMPTOMS
OF A HEART ATTACK.
USE CAUTION WHEN DRIVING
OR OPERATING MACHINERY.
COMMON SIDE EFFECTS
INCLUDE NAUSEA,
TROUBLE SLEEPING
AND UNUSUAL DREAMS.
WITH CHANTIX AND WITH
THE SUPPORT SYSTEM IT WORKED.
IT WORKED FOR ME.
[ Male Announcer ]
ASK YOUR DOCTOR IF CHANTIX
IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
♪ME AND YOU...
GHIRARDELLI
SQUARES CHOCOLATE...
♪A LITTLE RENDEZVOUS
SAVOR OUR LUSCIOUS
FILLING COMBINED
WITH OUR SLOW
MELTING CHOCOLATE.
♪THAT LITTLE REWARD FOR
ALL THE THINGS YOU DO.♪
ONLY FROM GHIRARDELLI.
EVERYTHING THAT'S
IN THEIR PRODUCTS.
BUT SC Johnson
ISN'T JUST A COMPANY.
WE'RE A FAMILY
WHO CARES ABOUT YOURS.
THAT'S WHY WE'RE WORKING
TO SHARE ALL OF OUR INGREDIENTS,
RIGHT DOWN TO THE FRAGRANCES
AND DYES.
SO WITH PRODUCTS LIKE Windex,
YOU KNOW WHAT YOU'RE BRINGING
INTO YOUR HOME.
GOING BEYOND
THE INDUSTRY STANDARD --
THAT'S THE FAMILY STANDARD.
♪
Just unroll it,
fill, top,
bake, and present.
That must have
taken you forever!
It was really tough.
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Pie Crust.
Let the Making Begin
KEEPING UP WITH THE KIDS
IS TOUGH, SO I DRINK EMERGEN-C.
WITH VITAMIN C
FOR IMMUNE SUPPORT
AND B VITAMINS
FOR NATURAL ENERGY,
I'M READY
FOR WHATEVER THEY GET INTO.
GET YOUR FREE SAMPLE
AT MYEMERGENC.COM.
STAY HEALTHY AND FEEL THE GOOD.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>>> PEOPLE ARE LOVING THOSE
MUFFINS, DAPHNE.
WELCOME BACK TO "THE CHEW'S"
COZY CHRISTMAS.
I SEEM TO BE STUFFED WITH
GLITTER.
EVERY TIME I GO LIKE THIS, MORE
GLITTER COMES OUT.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE IT'S COMING
FROM.
>> YEAH.
NEXT TIME I GET IN TROUBLE, I'M
GOING TO SAY I WAS CRAFTING.
>> I HAVE AN IDEA.
"IT'S FROM YOUR GLITTERY, GOLDEN
HEART."
>> THAT'S WHAT IT IS.
I'M ACTUALLY MADE OF GLITTER AND
GIN, YES.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> LOOSELY SUSPENDED WITH AN EGG
WHITE.
>> I FIND, THOUGH, EVEN WHEN I
TRIED REALLY HARD IN YOUR CRAFT
CORNER, I DON'T ALWAYS
UNDERSTAND HOW THINGS RESPOND.
>> WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
>> LIKE I PUT THE LITTLE SMILEY
FACE ON MY SNOWMAN AND THEN
ASSUMED A COUPLE MINUTES LATER,
IT WOULD BE DRY.
NOT DRY.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> OH.
>> I SMEARED HIS POOR, LITTLE
FACE.
>> THIS IS WHAT HAPPENED, YES.
PAINT MUST DRY.
JUST SO EVERYBODY KNOWS THAT AT
HOME, PAINT HAS TO DRY.
[ SIGHS ]
WELL, THE HOLIDAYS ARE A TIME TO
GIVE BACK TO THOSE IN NEED.
>> OH!
>> ALL RIGHT, LISTEN.
THIS IS IMPORTANT.
AS PART OF OUR ONGOING
PARTNERSHIP WITH FEEDING
AMERICA, WE HAVE DONATED MORE
THAN 75,000 MEALS.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
BUT, MORE IMPORTANTLY, IF YOU
WANT TO HELP, GO TO
FEEDINGAMERICA.ORG/THECHEW OR
TEXT "C-H-E-W" TO 50555 AND
REPLY "YES," AND YOU CAN DONATE
$10.
IF YOU ACT NOW, "THE CHEW" AND
DISNEY WILL MATCH YOUR GIFT
DOLLAR FOR DOLLAR, UP TO
$25,000.
>> WOW.
>> THAT MEANS THAT YOUR GIFT
WILL HAVE TWICE THE IMPACT IN
THE FIGHT AGAINST HUNGER.
[ APPLAUSE ]
SO GET OFF OF YOUR PHONES --
EXCUSE ME, GET ON YOUR PHONES,
AND MAKE A GIFT RIGHT NOW.
>>> ANOTHER THING I'D LIKE TO
TALK ABOUT IN THE SPIRIT OF
GIVING, EVERYONE IN OUR AUDIENCE
IS GOING HOME WITH A PANASONIC
GENIUS PRESTIGE MICROWAVE, JUST
IN TIME FOR THE HOLIDAYS!
YOU WON'T BELIEVE THE AMAZING
DISHES YOU CAN MAKE WITH ITS
EXCLUSIVE INVERTER TECHNOLOGY,
WHICH DELIVERS A PRECISE AND
CONSISTENT HEAT SO FOOD COOKS
EVENLY.
YOU CAN EVEN MAKE FULL MEALS IN
IT.
WE WHIPPED UP THIS DELICIOUS
RATATOUILLE!
THERE YOU GO.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
PANASONIC IS TAKING THE
GUESSWORK OUT OF YOUR HOLIDAY
MEALS WITH A PUSH OF THE
SENSOR-COOK BUTTON.
IT'S EXCITING.
YOU GUYS GET A NEW MICROWAVE.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> THAT'S A NO-JOKE GIFT.
>> NO JOKE!
>> WE'RE NOT FOOLING AROUND.
>> SWEET, YEAH!
>> WE ARE NOT FOOLING AROUND.
>> AND WE MADE RATATOUILLE, BUT
WE HAVE NO UTENSILS.
>> YEAH, WE JUST HAVE -- NO
SILVERWARE.
>> SCOOPS, SCOOPS.
>> THAT'S OKAY.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT IT.
>> THAT'S AMAZING.
YEAH.
>> THAT'S KIND OF --
>> HELLO, I'M CARLA.
>> CARLA JUST ATE RATATOUILLE
WITH A NAPKIN RING.
>> YOU KNOW, I'M EXCITED ABOUT
THIS RATATOUILLE OUT OF A
MICROWAVE, BUT I THINK I WOULD
USE REAL UTENSILS.
I'M NOT GONNA GO WITH THIS.
WELL, WE HAVE THE COOKIE DIPPER.
>> WE HAVE THE COOKIE DIPPER,
NOT HERE, ON THE TABLE.
>> BUT THIS IS A RATATOUILLE
DIPPER.
>> GREAT.
YOU COULD MARKET THAT.
>> LAST-MINUTE THINGS DO YOU GOT
TO GET DONE?
WHAT DO YOU HAVE TO GET DONE
STILL?
>> LIKE EVERYTHING, ALL OF MY
SHOPPING, YEAH.
>> EVERYTHING.
>> OH, EVERYTHING.
>> EVERYTHING, EVERYTHING.
DAPHNE?
>> STRESSING ME OUT, STRESSING
ME OUT.
STOP IT!
[ LAUGHTER ]
YOU'RE STRESSING ME OUT MORE!
>> I'M ALL SET UP.
I THINK I MAY NEED TO BUY ONE
RIBBON.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> I THINK I NEED WHAT MARIO
HAS -- STAFF.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> BUT MY STAFF IS ALL RUNNING
MY RESTAURANT.
>> I KNOW!
>> THIS IS PART OF MY LITTLE,
PERSONAL CRAFTINESS.
[ LAUGHTER ]
PREPARE, MY FRIENDS.
YOU CAN HAVE IT ALL, BUT THEY'VE
GOT TO DO IT EARLY.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> ONE WEEK AWAY.
ONE WEEK BEFORE CHRISTMAS.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US TODAY.
COME BACK TOMORROW FOR OUR
FAMILY HOLIDAY DINNER.
THE CONVERSATION CONTINUES ON
THECHEW.COM.
"GENERAL HOSPITAL" IS UP NEXT.
WE'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME.
HAVE A GREAT DAY.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Sabrina: UM, HELLO?
MISS COE?
>> Lucy: YOU CAN CALL ME "LUCY."
AND WELCOME.
WELCOME TO CoeCoe COSMETICS
CORPORATE HEADQUARTERS.
[ BOTH CHUCKLE ]
>> Felix: THANK YOU.
AND MIGHT I SAY, YOUR PICTURES
DO NOT DO YOU JUSTICE.
>> Sabrina: OH!
>> Felix: IS THAT YOUR NEW
CREAM-FOR-A-DAY FOUNDATION?
>> Lucy: YES, IT IS!
I SWEAR BY IT!
OH, WAIT A MINUTE.
I SHOULD BE THANKING YOU FOR
THAT YUMMY $50,000 IN SALES.
>> Felix: UM, ACTUALLY, I DON'T
HAVE $50,000 IN SALES.
SOONBU