>>> PREVIOUSLY ON BOTTOMS UP
AROUND THE WORLD WITH GUILLERMO.
>> I WENT TO THE NETHERLANDS.
THESE DUTCH GUYS SAY --
>> HAVE YOU EVER CONSIDERED
BECOMING A GENTLEMAN?
>> THEN I LEARNED ABOUT VODKA.
SOME JOURNEYS YOU MUST MAKE
ALONE.
A LOT HAS BEEN HAPPENING.
I'M VERY NERVOUS.
THERE'S ONE MORE THING I MUST DO
TO BECOME A GENTLEMAN.
THIS IS A REALLY LONG TUNNEL.
I'M READY.
WHAT DO YOU GUYS WANT?
>> I WANT YOU TO MAKE US A
PERFECT KETEL ONE MARTINI.
>> MARTINI.
OF COURSE.
>> SMALL.
>> IT'S NOT THE SIZE OF THE
BOAT.
IT'S THE OTHER STUFF.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> CHEERS, GENTLEMENS.
NEVER TRUST A BARTENDER.
I DON'T EVEN HAVE A BOAT.
MY NEW FRIENDS GAVE ME A
PRESENT.
>> IT'S A KETEL ONE MIXOLOGY
SET.
>> I KIND OF HAVE ONE LIKE THIS
ALREADY.
BUT I'LL TAKE IT.
TIME FOR A NEW ADVENTURE,
WHEREVER IT WILL TAKE ME.
>> KETEL ONE.
GENTLEMEN, THIS IS VODKA.
DRINK RESPONSIBLY.
>> Dicky: "JIMMY KIMMEL LIVE"
BACK IN TWO MINUTES WITH CARSON
DALY, ZACHARY KNIGHTON, AND
MUSIC FROM DAN DEACON.
OUT FROM THE SHALLOW END
TO FIND SOMETHING TRULY WORTHY
OF HIS SEARCH.
♪
INSPIRED BY 300 YEARS
OF TRADITION.
KETEL ONE.
GENTLEMEN, THIS IS VODKA.
DRINK RESPONSIBLY.
This season, give Craftsman
tools and give the gifts that
keep on giving.
CRAFTSMAN. GUYS'
FAVORITES GUARANTEED.
FIND IT AT SEARS.
DESCRIBE THE ROOM.
A BIG, OPEN SPACE.
SMELLS REALLY FRESH, MAN.
OH!
[ both laugh ]
FEBREZE? HOW ABOUT THAT?
YEAH.
FEBREZE
ANTI-CLOGGING TECHNOLOGY
KEEPS IT SMELLING FRESH.
FEBREZE. BREATHE HAPPY.
THIS YEAR GIVE 'EM
AN APPLEBEE'S GIFT CARD.
BUY 50 BUCKS
IN APPLEBEE'S GIFT CARDS,
AND YOU GET
A 10 DOLLAR BONUS CARD FREE.
A REAL BRIGHT IDEA.
A REAL BONUS.
ONLY AT APPLEBEE'S RESTAURANTS
OR APPLEBEES.COM.
SEE YOU TOMORROW.
>> Dicky: FROM HOLLYWOOD, IT'S
"JIMMY KIMMEL LIVE."
TONIGHT, CARSON DALY.
FROM "HAPPY ENDINGS", ZACHARY
KNIGHTON.
AND MUSIC FROM DAN DEACON, WITH
CLETO AND THE CLETONES.
AND NOW, MAKING SPIRITS BRIGHT,
HERE'S JIMMY KIMMEL!
>> Jimmy: WELCOME.
THANK YOU.
I'M JIMMY.
I'M THE HOST OF THE SHOW.
THANK YOU FOR WATCHING.
THANK YOU FOR WEARING YOUR
THURSDAY BEST TO BE HERE
TONIGHT.
EVERYONE ALL RIGHT?
YOU GUYS OKAY?
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
ARE ANY OF YOU COMPLETELY DONE
WITH YOUR CHRISTMAS SHOPPING?
>> YES!
>> Jimmy: KILL HER.
THERE ARE ONLY 11 DAYS BEFORE
CHRISTMAS EVE.
I GIVE A LOT OF GIFTS ON
CHRISTMAS AND I GET A LOT OF
GIFTS ON CHRISTMAS.
BUT I DON'T OPEN THEM RIGHT
AWAY.
I LIKE TO SAVE MY GIFTS AND I
OPEN THEM DURING SHARK WEEK.
IT'S JUST MORE EXCITING.
BY THE WAY, WHAT DO YOU DO WITH
A GIFT THAT YOU KNOW YOU'RE
NEVER GOING TO USE, YOU CAN'T
GIVE IT AWAY BECAUSE THE PERSON
MIGHT FIND OUT THAT YOU'VE GIVEN
IT TO SOMEBODY ELSE.
BUT MY POLICY, WHAT I DO IS I
KEEP IT FOR EXACTLY 38 MONTHS,
AND THEN I THROW IT AWAY.
OR GIVE IT AWAY OR SOMETHING.
IT'S RIDICULOUS.
BUT IT'S WHAT I DO.
IF YOU'RE ON FACEBOOK, AND BY
GOSH, I HOPE YOU ARE BECAUSE
IT'S A GREAT WAY TO KEEP IN
TOUCH WITH YOUR LOVED ONES.
THIS IS THE TIME OF THE YEAR
WHEN YOUR NEWS FEED BECOMES A
CONSTANT STREAM OF PICTURES OF
KIDS ON SANTA'S LAP.
KIDS DON'T ALWAYS LIKE SANTA.
A LOT OF KIDS GO NUTS WHEN YOU
HAND THEM OVER TO SANTA, WHICH
IF YOU THINK ABOUT IT IS A
REASONABLE REACTION TO HAVE.
IT'S A GOOD INSTINCT.
WE DID THIS LAST YEAR, A
GUESSING GAME, CALLED SANTA'S
LAP OR FLU SHOT?
[ APPLAUSE ]
I'M GOING TO SHOW YOU A CLOSE-UP
OF A CHILD'S FACE.
YOU HAVE TO GUESS WHETHER THAT
CHILD IS SITTING ON SANTA'S LAP
OR GETTING A FLU SHOT.
OKAY?
LET'S BEGIN.
HERE WE GO.
OKAY, SANTA'S LAP OR A FLU SHOT?
LET'S SEE THE FULL PHOTOGRAPH.
FLU SHOT.
NEXT UP.
ALL RIGHT, WE HAVE SOME MIXED
ANSWERS HERE.
LET'S SEE.
SANTA'S LAP.
WHO DO WE HAVE NEXT?
MOST EVERYONE IS SAYING SANTA.
A COUPLE FLU SHOTS.
SANTA.
IT'S A DOUBLE WHAMMY THERE.
ALL RIGHT.
EVERYONE SEEMS CERTAIN THAT
THAT'S A FLU SHOT.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S HAVE A LOOK.
YEAH, THAT IS A FLU SHOT.
HE'S JUST SCARED OF HER HAIR.
OKAY.
SANTA?
LET'S HAVE A LOOK.
SANTA.
SANTA IS DRESSED A LITTLE BIT
TOO AVANT-GARDE FOR MY LIKING.
WE HAVE ONE MORE.
THERE'S THE FACE.
THERE'S THE EXPRESSION.
AND WE SAY FLU SHOT?
ALL RIGHT, LET'S TAKE A LOOK.
AT THE A -- OH, SANTA.
IT'S SANTA GIVING HIM A FLU
SHOT.
SPEAKING OF CHRISTMAS AND KIDS,
LAST NIGHT ON THE SHOW, WE ASKED
A BUNCH OF KIDS OUT ON HOLLYWOOD
BOULEVARD TO TELL US THE STORY
OF CHRISTMAS AND WE PIECED IT
TOGETHER AND IT WAS CUTE.
BUT ONE KID WE LEFT OUT BECAUSE
HE GAVE SUCH A LENGTHY RESPONSE,
WE WERE UNABLE TO EDIT IT.
WE ASKED THIS KID ONE QUESTION,
HE TALKED FOR NINE AND A HALF
MINUTES STRAIGHT.
NOW, OBVIOUSLY, WE'RE NOT GOING
TO SHOW ALL NINE AND A HALF
MINUTES, BUT THIS IS A LOT OF
IT.
WE FAST FORWARDED THROUGH SOME
PARTS.
HERE NOW WITH HIS VERSION OF THE
STORY OF CHRISTMAS, A YOUNG LAD
NAMED LIAM.
>> WHAT IS YOUR NAME?
>> LIAM.
>> AND HOW OLD ARE YOU, LIAM?
>> 4.
>> TELL ME THE STORY OF
CHRISTMAS.
>> CHRISTMAS -- THERE ARE
PRESENTS.
THERE ARE REINDEER.
IF IT DIDN'T HAVE REINDEERS -- I
COULD JUST ASK THEM MYSELF.
EACH DAY IS CHRISTMAS FOR ONE,
TWO, THREE, FOUR, FIVE, SIX,
SEVEN, EIGHT, NINE, TEN, 11, 12,
13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20,
21, 22, 23, 24, 25 -- 25.
GOT TO BUILD A SNOWMAN, TOO.
GOT TO GIVE IT FOOD.
SO THEY CAN DO IT.
A PRESENT AT MY SCHOOL.
>> WHAT DID I MISS?
>> I TALKED ABOUT MY SCHOOL.
>> OH, YOU WERE TELLING THEM
ABOUT THE SCHOOL.
>> SO, I SAID I DID GET
CHOCOLATE.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> JUST SLIGHTLY LONGER THAN ALL
THE "HARRY POTTER" NOVELS.
WHAT LANGUAGE DO KIDS IN ENGLAND
SPEAK?
>>> TONIGHT AT MIDNIGHT, THE
PREMIERE OF "THE HOBBIT: AN
UNEXPECTED JOURNEY."
THE FIRST OF THREE MOVIES BASED
ON THE BOOK "THE HOBBIT."
AS A MOVIE, NOW THAT WE HAVE
"GAME OF THRONES," THE HOBBIT
SEEMS KIND OF TAME.
WHY WATCH PEOPLE FIGHT A DRAGON
IN A MOVIE, WHEN I CAN WATCH
THEM FIGHT A DRAGON NAKED ON
HBO?
DIRECTOR PETER JACKSON USED SOME
UNIQUE FILM MAKING MAGIC TO FILM
THIS.
THE HOBBIT WAS SHOT AT 48 FRAMES
PER SECOND.
HE BELIEVES IT MAKES THE FILM
LOOK MORE REALISTIC.
SOME OF THE PEOPLE WHO HAVE SEEN
IT IN 3-D SAID THE INCREASED
FRAME RATE MADE THEM FEEL
NAUSEATED.
THE PRODUCERS SAY THESE CLAIMS
ARE UNFOUNDED, BUT THEIR ADS
FROM A LEGAL STANDPOINT SEEM TO
BE PLAYING IT SAFE.
>> FROM DIRECTOR PETER JACKSON
COMES THE STIRRING TALE OF BILL
BOW BAGGINS AND A QUEST LIKE NO
OTHER.
ENJOY THE MAGIC, THE MYSTERY,
AND THE ADVENTURE.
"THE HOBBIT."
"THE HOBBIT" IS NOT FOR
EVERYONE.
SIDE EFFECTS MAY INCLUDE DRY
MOUTH, NAUSEA, VOMITING AND HEAD
ACHE.
IF SYMPTOMS DO NOT IMPROVE AFTER
30 MINUTES, STOP WATCHING "THE
HOBBIT" AND SEE A DOCTOR.
ERECTIONS LASTING MORE THAN FOUR
HOUR
HOURS.
ASK YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT "THE
HOBBIT."
BRING A BUCKET.
IN THEATERS EVERYWHERE.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> Jimmy: THE NOMINATION FOR THE
GOLDEN GLOBES WERE ANNOUNCED
THIS MORNING.
IF YOU GOT A SCREAMING PHONE
CALL AT 4:00 A.M., YOU WERE
EITHER NOMINATED FOR A GOLDEN
GLOBE OR YOU'RE CHARLIE SHEEN'S
GIRLFRIEND.
THE GOLDEN GLOBES ARE VERY
IMPORTANT BECAUSE WHOEVER WINS
THE GOLDEN GLOBE MAY OR MAY NOT
WIN THE OSCAR.
[ LAUGHTER ]
AND STEVEN SPIELBERG'S MOVIE
"LINCOLN" HAD THE MOST
NOMINATIONS OF ANY FILM THIS
YEAR.
SEVEN.
"LINCOLN" WAS NOMINATED FOR BEST
PICTURE, BEST DIRECTOR, BEST
BEARD WITHOUT A MUSTACHE, AND
FURRIEST TOP HAT.
SO THAT'S IMPRESSIVE.
GOOD NEWS FOR iPHONE USERS.
AS YOU MAY RECALL, APPLE REMOVED
THE GOOGLE MAPS APP FROM THE
iPHONE OPERATING SYSTEM AND
REPLACED IT WITH THEIR OWN
NAVIGATION APP, APPLE MAPS,
WHICH DIDN'T WORK WELL.
IT GOT PEOPLE LOST.
SO LAST NIGHT, APPLE UNBANNED
GOOGLE MAPS FROM THE PHONE,
WHICH MEANS iPHONE OWNERS CAN
FIND THINGS AGAIN.
WHICH I GUESS MEANS WHITE PEOPLE
ARE GOING TO HAVE TO FIND
SOMETHING NEW TO COMPLAIN ABOUT.
IT IS A LITTLE BIT WEIRD,
THOUGH, BECAUSE YOU CAN DOWNLOAD
THE NEW GOOGLE MAPS APP, BUT
APPLE DOESN'T ALLOW YOU TO
DELETE APPLE MAPS.
WHICH MEANS APPLE MAPS WILL
ALWAYS BE THERE ON YOUR HOME
SCREEN WATCHING YOU USE GOOGLE.
IT'S LIKE DATING A NEW GIRL
WHILE YOU'RE STILL LIVING WITH
YOUR EX.
I MISS THE APPLE MAPS.
FOR ME, IT WAS LIKE A CHOOSE
YOUR OWN ADVENTURE KIND OF
THING.
NEVER KNEW WHERE I MIGHT END UP.
GOOGLE IS ALSO MAKING IT HARDER
NOW TO FIND PORNOGRAPHY.
GOOGLE JUST CHANGED THEIR IMAGE
SEARCH ALGORITHM, SO IT WILL
ONLY BRING UP PORNOGRAPHIC
IMAGES IF THE SEARCHER MAKES IT
EXPLICITLY CLEAR THAT THAT'S
WHAT THEY'RE LOOKING FOR.
THEY WOULD HAVE GOTTEN TO THIS
SOONER, BUT THEY WERE TOO BUSY
DESIGNING A LOGO FOR NATIONAL
ROOT BEER DAY.
I'M GOING TO THROW ALL OF YOU
OUT, I SWEAR TO GOD.
I WILL CLEAR THIS ROOM.
WE WILL GET A FRESH NEW
AUDIENCE.
ANYWAY, SO NOW YOU'LL HAVE TO
ASK SIRI FOR BORN.
OR BING.
DOES BING REALLY EXIST OR IS IT
LIKE THE CHUPACABRA?
DID ANY OF YOU WATCH THE
12-12-12 BENEFIT CONCERT LAST
NIGHT?
IT WAS TO RAISE MONEY FOR
HURRICANE SANDY RELIEF.
BRUCE SPRINGSTEEN, BON JOVI,
BILLY JOEL, ERIC CLAPTON, PAUL
McCARTNEY PLAYED WITH THE
REMAINING MEMBERS OF NIRVANA.
STEVE BUSCEMI APPEARED ALONGSIDE
NEW YORK'S DEPARTMENT OF
SANITATION, SOME OF WHOM WERE
VERY EXCITED TO SEE HIM.
>> PROVIDING THE GRAY BEARDS
WITH EMERGENCY FUNDS TO SUSTAIN
THEIR POST-STORM ASSISTANCE.
COME ON.
JUST COME ON IN.
YEAH, YOU, TOO.
COME ON IN.
>> LET'S GO, BUSCEMI, I LOVE
YOU!
>> OW.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> HE SUFFERED THREE BROKEN
RIBS, A CONCUSSION AND A BRUISED
TAILBONE, BUT HE'S GOING TO BE
OKAY.
FLORIDA IS ABOUT TO HIT A
SURPRISING MILESTONE.
SOMETIME NEXT WEEK, FLORIDA IS
EXPECTED TO ISSUE ITS ONE
MILLIONTH LICENSE TO CARRY A
CONCEALED WEAPON.
THEY LOWERED THE APPLICATION AND
RENEWAL FEES, SO NOW IT'S EVEN
HIGHER.
PEOPLE IN FLORIDA NEED GUNS
BECAUSE THEY HAVE SOMETHING
CALLED ALLIGATORS THERE.
CARRYING A GUN IS THE THING TO
DO IN FLORIDA.
THIS HAPPENED AT THE MIAMI SEA
AQUARIUM YESTERDAY.
WHEN IT GETS TO THE SEA
CREATURES --
[ LAUGHTER ]
WHILE WE'RE ON THE TOPIC OF
AQUATIC ANIMALS WITH A TASTE FOR
BLOOD, THIS IS A CRAZY VIDEO.
IT WAS SHOT OFF THE WEST COAST
OF IRELAND.
SOME FRIENDS WERE ON A BOAT
TRYING TO GET A GOOD LOOK AT A
SHARK.
ONE GUY IS KIND OF LEANING OVER
THE EDGE AND HIS FRIEND THOUGHT
IT WOULD BE FUNNY TO SHOVE HIM
IN THE WATER.
THOSE ARE SOME FRIENDS.
LOOK AT THIS.
THERE'S THE SHARK.
HE TOOK IT WELL.
I WOULD HAVE OBJECTED.
THIS IS A STRANGE STORY.
LAST WEEK IN GRAPELAND, TEXAS, A
LEMUR -- A PET LEMUR NAMED KEANU
BIT A MAIL CARRIER, WHOSE LAST
NAME IS -- ANY GUESSES?
>> REEVES!
>> Jimmy: THAT'S RIGHT.
KEANU THE LEMUR BIT HER ON THE
HAND.
I LIKE A LEMUR WITH A SENSE OF
HUMOR.
I REALLY DO.
IF THAT ISN'T WEIRD ENOUGH, IN
OHIO ON TUESDAY, A GUY NAMED
SCOTT HALL HAD HIS EYEBROW
BITTEN OFF BY A MAN NAMED ROGER
OATES.
HALL & OATES.
THE POLICE SHOWED UP AND STARTED
LAUGHING WHEN THEY TOOK THEIR
NAMES.
IMAGINE YOU GET YOUR EYEBROW
BITTEN OFF AND POLICE SHOW UP
AND START -- BY THE WAY, HOW DO
YOU EVEN BITE AN EYEBROW OFF?
YOU REALLY NEED TO KIND OF
SCRAPE IT OFF.
IT WOULD BE LIKE EATING CANDIED
BUTTONS, WOULDN'T IT?
IF YOU'RE IN ANY WAY NAMED AFTER
A CELEBRITY OF ANY KIND, BE
CAREFUL, THESE THINGS HAPPEN IN
THREES.
WE'RE NOW JUST A FEW WEEKS AWAY
FROM POTENTIALLY FALLING OFF
WHAT THEY CALL THE FISCAL CLIFF.
VERY BASICALLY, CONGRESS PUT A
HUGE PACKAGE OF TAX INCREASES
AND SPENDING CUTS IN PLACE FOR
THE BEGINNING OF 2013.
MANY EXPERTS BELIEF IF IT GOES
INTO EFFECT, IT WILL PUSH US
INTO ANOTHER RECESSION, SO THEY
NEED TO REACH A BUDGET
AGREEMENT.
UNFORTUNATELY, THEY'RE UNABLE TO
REACH AN AGREEMENT ON ANYTHING
IN CONGRESS, SO THIS COULD TURN
OUT VERY BADLY.
IT'S AN IMPORTANT HURDLE WE HAVE
TO CLEAR, AND A LOT OF PEOPLE
HAVE STRONG OPINIONS ON IT.
BUT I WONDERED HOW MANY PEOPLE
ACTUALLY EVEN KNOW WHAT IT IS.
SO WE WENT OUT ON THE STREET
TODAY TO ASK THEM ABOUT THE SO
CALLED FISCAL CLIFF.
>> ARE YOU WORRIED ABOUT THE
FISCAL CLIFF?
>> IT COULD MAKE A DIFFERENCE IN
LIFE.
I MEAN, IT ALL DEPENDS ON HOW
YOU LOOK AT IT.
>> AND WHAT EXACTLY IS THE
FISCAL CLIFF?
>> I'M NOT SURE EXACTLY WHAT
THAT IS.
BUT, I MEAN, IF YOU REALLY THINK
ABOUT IT, I GUESS IT COULD CAUSE
SOMETHING, IF YOU, LIKE,
RESEARCHED IT OR WHATEVER.
>> ARE YOU WORRIED ABOUT THE
FISCAL CLIFF?
>> YEAH, KIND OF.
>> WHAT EXACTLY IS THE FISCAL
CLIFF?
>> IT'S A RAISE IN TAXES AND --
YEAH.
NOW I'M GOING TO LOOK LIKE A
FOOL.
I DON'T KNOW.
[ LAUGHTER ]
UH-HUH.
I DON'T KNOW.
>> ARE YOU WORRIED ABOUT THE
FISCAL CLIFF?
REQUI
>> I GUESS, YEAH.
>> WHAT IS IT?
>> SOMETHING TO DO FINANCIALLY.
YEAH.
THAT'S ALL THAT I CAN TELL YOU.
>> WHY ARE YOU WORRIED?
>> BECAUSE YOU HAVE A WORRIED
LOOK ON YOUR FACE.
>> IT'S NOT GOOD.
I KNOW THAT.
SO YEAH.
>> DO YOU KNOW WHAT IT IS?
>> NO, I REALLY DON'T.
YOU GO OFF THE CLIFF.
>> ARE YOU WORRIED ABOUT THE
FISCAL CLIFF?
>> NO.
>> WHAT IS IT?
>> WELL, THE FISCAL CLIFF I KNOW
IS MR. HUXTABLE.
THAT'S THE ONLY ONE I KNOW.
>> WELL, YEAH.
YOU GOT A MICROPHONE IN MY FACE.
YEAH.
I'M DONE.
>> Jimmy: WE'RE GOING TO GIVE
HIM HALF CREDIT FOR THAT ONE.
IT'S THURSDAY NIGHT.
IT'S TIME FOR OUR WEEKLY TRIBUTE
TO WHERE WE BLEEP THINGS.
IT'S UNNECESSARY CENSORSHIP.
>> I THINK -- I TRULY BELIEVE
THAT THEY HAVE THE BIGGEST
[ BLEEP ] IN THE NFL.
>> I WAS TAKEN IN A PRO VAKTIVE
PHOTO BUT I WAS SITTING ON
SANTA'S [ BLEEP ].
>> EMILY BLUNT, SALMON [ BLEEP ]
IN THE YEMEN.
>> I WANTED TO TAKE SOME TIME
AND JUST REALLY [ BLEEP ]
MYSELF.
>> AMY, ARE YOU GOING TO HELP US
[ BLEEP ]?
>> I THINK THE REPUBLICANS ARE
REALLY REACHING THE END OF LINE.
THEY'RE HOPING OBAMA WILL SHOW
HIS [ BLEEP ].
>> THAT'S WHAT I'M TALKING
ABOUT.
>> YOU CAN [ BLEEP ] ME IF YOU
WANT.
>> NEVER.
I MIGHT [ BLEEP ] YOUR BUM IF
YOU'RE NAUGHTY.
>> I DON'T KNOW IF YOU KNOW, BUT
HE HAS A BIG [ BLEEP ].
AND I MEAN A BIG [ BLEEP ].
>> THIS ONE GUY SAID I [ BLEEP ]
THIS GIRL'S BREASTS BEFORE I
[ BLEEP ] HER FACE.
>> DANIELLE.
>> [ BLEEP ] FESTIVAL.
>> THAT IS CORRECT.
>> I WILL TRAP SANTA IN MY BOX,
FORT KNOX AND MAKE HIM
[ BLEEP ].
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> Jimmy: WE'VE GOT A GOOD SHOW
TONIGHT.
FROM "HAPPY ENDINGS," ZACHARY
KNIGHTON.
WE HAVE MUSIC FROM DAN DEACON.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH CARSON
DALY, SO STICK AROUND.
HOW IT FEELS TO CHEW 5 Gum.
[ beads rattling ]
[ bass thudding ]
SPEARMINT THAT TINGLES
AS YOU CHEW.
STIMULATE YOUR SENSES.
5 Gum.
NOW IN Micro Pack.
♪
[Spider-Man]
WE GOT THIS.
♪
[Mom]
THIS HERO STUFF IS EASY!
[ Male Announcer ] EVERY TIME
YOU SAY NO TO A CIGARETTE
YOU CELEBRATE A LITTLE WIN.
NICORETTE GUM HELPS CALM
YOUR CRAVINGS
AND MAKES YOU LESS IRRITABLE.
QUIT ONE CIGARETTE AT A TIME.
>> Dicky: IF YOU'RE GOING TO BE
IN THE L.A. AREA AND WANT TO SEE
THE SHOW, CALL 866-JIMMY TIX OR
GO TO JIMMYKIMMELLIVE.COM.
♪
I'LL HELP YOU.
[ Grandma ] OK.
♪
AH.
THEN WE WILL ALL
DO IT TOGETHER.
TREATS.
TEETS...TEETS...
TEETS...
YEAH, LOOK AT THIS!
[ Female Announcer ] IT SEEMS
LIKE THE BEST FAMILY TRADITIONS
ALWAYS START IN THE KITCHEN.
♪
HAPPY HOLIDAYS...
FROM Rice Krispies.
[ all kids ] FASTER!
OK, WHAT'S FAST?
UM, MY MOM'S CAR
AND A CHEETAH.
OKAY.
A SPACESHIP.
AND WHAT'S SLOW?
MY GRANDMA'S SLOW.
WOULD YOU LIKE IT BETTER
IF SHE WAS FAST?
I BET SHE WOULD LIKE IT
IF SHE WAS FAST.
HM, MAYBE GIVE HER
SOME TURBO BOOSTERS.
TAPE A CHEETAH
TO HER BACK.
TO HER BACK?
SEEMS LIKE YOU HAVE
THOUGHT ABOUT THIS BEFORE.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S NOT COMPLICATED.
FASTER IS BETTER.
AND THE IPHONE 5
DOWNLOADS FASTEST ON AT&T 4G.
♪
FOR THEIR ANNUAL FOOTBALL TRIP.
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE.
TRAGICALLY, THEIR BUDDY
GOT SACKED BY BLACKOUTS.
BUT IT'S OUR TRADITION!
THAT'S ROUGHING
THE CARD HOLDER.
BUT WITH
THE Capital One Venture Card
YOU GET DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE.
[ cheering ]
ANY FLIGHT, ANYTIME.
THE SCOREBOARD DOESN'T LIE.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET? HUT!
I HAVE ME ON MY FANTASY TEAM.
he opened up
Jake's very private world.
At first, Jake's family
thought they saved Ziggy,
but his connection with Jake
has been a lifesaver.
For a love this strong,
his family only feeds him Iams.
Compared to other
leading brands,
it has 50% more
animal protein...
...to help keep Ziggy's body
as strong as a love
that reaches further
than anyone's words.
Iams. Keep Love Strong.
McDonald's TENDER,
JUICY Chicken McNuggets
IN SPICY BUFFALO
AND CREAMY RANCH SAUCE.
JUST $4.99 FOR 20 OF YOUR
FAVORITE Chicken McNuggets.
MORE WAYS TO LOVE McNuggets.
♪
>> Jimmy: TONIGHT ON THE
PROGRAM, IF YOU WATCH THE SHOW
"HAPPY ENDINGS," YOU KNOW HIM AS
DAVE.
IN REAL LIFE, HE HAS ANOTHER
NAME, AND THAT NAME IS ZACHARY
KNIGHTON.
HE IS HERE WITH US TONIGHT.
AND WITH MUSIC FROM THIS ALBUM,
IT'S CALLED "AMERICA" NAMED
AFTER THE COUNTRY, DAN DEACON
FROM THE BUD LIGHT STAGE.
DAN IS VERY CLEVER.
HE DEVELOPED AN iPHONE APP AND
IT LETS THE AUDIENCE INTERACT
WITH THE MUSIC AS IT PLAYS.
IT'S LIKE WITCHCRAFT, SO STAY UP
TO SEE THAT.
MAKE SURE TO WATCH US NEXT WEEK.
OUR GUESTS WILL INCLUDE HUGH
JACKMAN, SAMUEL L. JACKSON,
JENNA FISCHER, THE ENTIRE CAST
OF "JERSEY SHORE" WILL BE HERE,
AND MUSIC FROM TWO CHAINS.
OUR FIRST GUEST TONIGHT, FIVE
NIGHTS A WEEK ON LATE NIGHT TV,
AND HEARD FIVE MORNINGS A WEEK
ON THE RADIO, CHILD LABORERS IN
TAIWAN GET MORE TIME OFF THAN HE
DOES, THE TIRELESS HOST OF "LAST
CALL" AND "THE VOICE", PLEASE
WELCOME CARSON DALY.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> IT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU.
THANK YOU FOR BOOKING ME.
I FEEL LIKE THAT'S THE ONLY
CHANCE I GET TO SEE YOU.
>> Jimmy: WE DON'T SEE EACH
OTHER MUCH BECAUSE YOU HAVE 12
JOBS IS REALLY WHY.
>> WELL, YES.
WELL, I NEED THEM.
BUT I HAVEN'T ACTUALLY SEEN YOU
SINCE YOU GOT BACK FROM BROOKLYN
AND I WANTED TO TELL YOU HOW
AWESOME THAT WEEK WAS.
>> Jimmy: OH, THANKS.
IT WAS GREAT.
IT WAS A VERY EXCITING WEEK, AS
YOU KNOW.
>> HOW WAS IT INTERVIEWING
LETTERMAN?
>> Jimmy: DAVID LETTERMAN?
>> YES, DAVID LETTERMAN.
>> IT WAS PRETTY CRAZY FOR ME.
>> YOU MIGHT KNOW THIS ABOUT US,
BUT I MET JIMMY OVER 25 YEARS
AGO.
MY REAL NAME IS CARSON.
HE REFUSED TO CALL ME CARSON
BECAUSE HIS INFATUATION WITH
LETTERMAN IS SOMETHING THAT HE'S
HAD FOREVER.
HE LITERALLY WOULD NOT CALL ME
CARSON.
TO WATCH YOU FINALLY SIT THERE
AND INTERVIEW HIM WAS ONE OF THE
GREATEST THINGS I'VE SEEN.
YOU WERE FANTASTIC.
[ APPLAUSE ]
IT WAS GREAT.
>> Jimmy: WE'VE KNOWN EACH OTHER
SINCE YOU WERE 12 YEARS OLD AND
THEN YOU WERE MY INTERN AT A
RADIO STATION.
WE WORKED TOGETHER IN PALM
SPRINGS, CALIFORNIA.
I MET YOUR PARENTS AND THAT'S
HOW WE MET, FOR THOSE OF US WHO
CARE.
CARSON USED TO BABYSIT MY
DAUGHTER.
>> I THINK PEOPLE THINK YOU GAVE
ME MY BIG BREAKING BUT IT'S
REALLY BEEN A LIFE OF TORTURE.
I SEE ALL THESE BIG HOLLYWOOD
STARS AND CONGRATULATE YOU ON
11:30 AND I'M NOT SO HAPPY ABOUT
IT.
>> Jimmy: WHY?
>> BECAUSE YOU'VE TORTURED ME ON
A BUDGET SO LONG AND NOW YOU'RE
GOING TO BECOME PROBABLY THE
MOST POWERFUL MAN IN TELEVISION
AND I'M FEARFUL OF HOW YOU WILL
TORTURE ME.
>> Jimmy: IT WILL BE FINE.
>> YOU HAD NO TOOLS TO DO IT AND
YOU DID IT QUITE WELL.
>> Jimmy: WELL, I FELT LIKE I
HAD TO SHAPE YOU AND I FELT LIKE
YOUR LIFE HAD BEEN TOO EASY UP
TO THAT POINT.
>> I HAD TO BE A SPEEDO WITH A
COWBOY HAT AND SHAVED?
THAT'S SHAPING ME?
>> Jimmy: THAT'S HOW YOU GOT
YOUR BIG FOLLOWING, IN THE
SPEEDO AND THE COWBOY HAT.
YOU DO YOUR LATE NIGHT SHOW.
YOU'LL BE ON LATER AFTER US.
>> MANY HOURS LATER.
>> Jimmy: AND THEN YOU GET UP IN
THE MORNING AND DO YOUR RADIO
SHOW EVERY MORNING.
AND IT'S EXHAUSTING, YES?
AND YOU HAVE A LITTLE BABY GIRL
AT HOME.
>> I DO.
THANK YOU FOR COMING TO VISIT
HER.
>> Jimmy: AND A LITTLE BOY AT
HOME.
I HAVE NOT BEEN TO VISIT HER
YET.
>> HE WAS THE FIRST ONE OF MY
FRIENDS -- MY SON, FIRST ONE OF
MY FRIENDS TO KNOCK ON THE DOOR,
MADE THE DRIVE ALL THE WAY.
BUSY GUY.
>> Jimmy: I WAS LOST.
>> CAMERA, FOOD, GIFTS.
WHERE'S THE BOY?
AND MY SON COMES OUT, HE WANTS
TO SEE HIS PAL'S KID.
NOW I'VE GOT A DAUGHTER, SHE'S 3
MONTHS.
YOU HAVEN'T SEEN HER A LICK YET.
I HAVE THREE JOBS.
WHAT HAVE YOU BEEN DOING?
>> I WAS HOSTING THE MEMMYS.
THAT WAS VERY CONVENIENT FOR ME.
I FEEL BAD THAT I HAVE NOT SEEN
HER.
BUT SHE'S VERY CUTE FROM THE
PICTURES.
>> HOW MANY TIMES HAVE YOU BEEN
TO THE WHITE HOUSE SINCE I'VE
HAD MY DAUGHTER?
>> Jimmy: TWICE.
ONCE.
ONE TIME.
>> HOW UNPATRIOTIC.
YOU CHOOSE THIS COUNTRY OVER
YOUR FRIEND'S DAUGHTER.
>> Jimmy: I AM SUPPOSED TO
TORMENT YOU, NOT THE OTHER WAY
AROUND.
LET'S GET BACK TO YOU.
YOU ARE ON "THE VOICE."
YOU HOST THE SHOW.
IT'S A GREAT SHOW.
IT'S DOING VERY WELL.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Jimmy: YOU LOVE BLAKE
SHELTON.
HE'S A COUNTRY SINGER P HE'S
WOULD HAVE BEEN THE JUDGES ON
THE SHOW.
>> I LIKE THE GUY.
HE'S A COLD-BLOODED KILLER.
HE'S A HUNTER.
HE HUNTS FOR EVERYTHING.
>> Jimmy: HE KILLS THINGS.
>> OH, YES.
>> Jimmy: WHAT KINDS OF THINGS
DOES HE KILL?
>> LIKE ANIMALS, VARIOUS SORTS.
WHEN WE'RE NOT SHOOTING HE GOES
BACK TO OKLAHOMA AND JUST STARTS
TEXTING DEAD CARCASSES TO ME.
LIKE HE'S HOLDING A HEAD OF
SOMETHING.
>> Jimmy: WHEN YOU'RE NOT
SHOOTING, HE'S STILL SHOOTING.
>> HE'S A GREAT GUY.
>> Jimmy: ARE YOU A FAN OF HIS
MUSIC?
>> I AM, ACTUALLY.
HE HAS THIS SONG CALLED "DRINK
ON IT" WHICH IS ONE OF THE BEST
SONGS I'VE EVER HEARD.
>> Jimmy: CAN YOU NAME ONE MORE
OF HIS SONGS?
>> NO.
>> Jimmy: WELL, CARSON, YOU'RE
RIGHT.
>> WHAT IS THE 11:35 VERSION OF
THIS?
DOES HE COME OUT?
>> Jimmy: IT'S EXACTLY THE SAME.
I WANT TO DO SOMETHING NICE FOR
YOU.
>> REALLY?
I'M TERRIFIED RIGHT NOW.
YOU'VE NEVER SAID THAT BEFORE.
>> Jimmy: YOU KNOW THAT YOU HAVE
HAD SOME TROUBLE -- MY COUSIN
SAL KEEPS A LIST OF THE 20 MOST
RECOGNIZABLE PEOPLE --
>> OH, NO.
>> Jimmy: WHO STARTED THEIR
CAREERS ON MTV.
>> THIS IS THE TOPIC OF DEBATE
FOR MANY YEARS.
>> Jimmy: YOU HAD SOME TROUBLE
CRACKING THE TOP 20.
>> COUSIN SAL HAS TROUBLE
BELIEVING THAT I'M IN THE TOP
20.
>> Jimmy: EXACTLY.
COUSIN SAL HAS TROUBLE.
BUT I WANT TO PRESENT SOMETHING
TO YOU RIGHT NOW.
AND LADIES AND GENTLEMEN, HERE
IS MY COUSIN SAL WITH HIS LIST
FOR 2012 OF COUSIN SAL'S TOP 20
MTV-BORN CELEBRITIES.
AGAIN, THESE ARE CELEBRITIES
THAT GOT THEIR START ON MTV AND
HAVE NOW GONE ON TO BIGGER
THINGS.
>> I GOT TO BE SOMEWHERE THERE.
>> WE'RE GOING TO SEE.
>> Jimmy: HERE WE GO.
>> ALL RIGHT.
HERE WE GO.
NUMBER ONE, ADAM SANDLER.
NUMBER TWO, JOHNNY KNOXVILLE.
>> Jimmy: THAT'S VERY GOOD.
>> NUMBER THREE, PAULY SHORE.
NUMBER FOUR, SNOOKI.
NUMBER FIVE, THE SITUATION.
NUMBER SIX, SHARON OSBOURNE.
NUMBER SEVEN, KELLY OSBOURNE.
>> Jimmy: OKAY.
>> NUMBER EIGHT, JACK OSBOURNE.
>> THAT'S THE WHOLE SHOW RIGHT
THERE.
>> NUMBER NINE, STEVE-O.
NUMBER TEN, DOWNTOWN JULIE
BROWN.
>> NICE LADY, AND ALL.
>> NUMBER 11 -- IT'S MY LIST.
YOU MAKE YOUR OWN LIST.
NUMBER 11, THE OTHER JULIE
BROWN.
>> Jimmy: OKAY.
>> NUMBER 12, DENIS LEARY.
>> HE SHOULD BE HIGHER, I THINK.
>> 13, CARMEN ELECTRA.
NUMBER 14, JENNY McCARTHY.
NUMBER 15, DR. DREW.
>> VERY POPULAR.
>> NUMBER 16 --
>> [ BLEEP ].
>> WHAT AN EGOTIST.
NUMBER 16, TILA TEQUILA.
NUMBER 17, TOM GREEN.
NUMBERS 18 AND 19, COLIN AND
MARTHA QUINN.
>> Jimmy: COUSIN SAL, WHAT IS
THE 20th?
>> NUMBER 20 MOST POPULAR
MTV-BORN CELEBRITY, CARSON DALY.
>> YES!
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> THANK YOU.
>> Jimmy: I'M SO HAPPY FOR YOU.
CARSON DALY, EVERYONE.
THE TWO-NIGHT SEASON FINALE OF
"THE VOICE" STARTS MONDAY NIGHT
AT 8:00 ON NBC.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH ZACHARY
KNIGHTON.
>> Dicky: PORTIONS OF "JIMMY
KIMMEL LIVE" ARE BROUGHT TO YOU
BY KEURIG.
BREW WHAT YOU LOVE.
for Net10 Wireless.
Doug's family doesn't have that.
We aren't Doug's family.
I can't be seen on some pre-paid
phone!!
You could have any of these top
smartphones at half the
cost of our plan.
Use positive reinforcement.
We just wanted to fit in.
You fit in right here.
Welcome to the next generation
of family plans.
Fifty dollars the first line, 40
dollars each new line with
unlimited everything.
Visit Net10Wireless.com
This season, give Craftsman
tools and give the gifts that
keep on giving.
CRAFTSMAN. GUYS'
FAVORITES GUARANTEED.
FIND IT AT SEARS.
GO OLIVE GARDEN'S
2 FOR $25 ITALIAN DINNER.
ALL THE SALAD AND
BREADSTICKS YOU WANT.
CHOOSE A SHARABLE APPETIZER.
THEN TWO DELICIOUS ENTREES
LIKE SMOKED MOZZARELLA CHICKEN.
THREE COURSES,
TWO PEOPLE, JUST $25.
GO OLIVE GARDEN.
I'M A SHEETS GIRL,
BUT I DON'T JUST PUT'EM IN THE
DRYER TO FRESHEN UP MY CLOTHES.
I PUT'EM IN MY SHOES,
I PUT'EM IN MY CAR,
I PUT'EM IN MY VASES.
GIRL, I BEEN PUT'N'EM
FOR AS LONG AS I CAN REMEMBER.
[ Male Announcer ]
HOW DO YOU GET YOUR BOUNCE?
[ Woman ] SHEETS, I PUT'EM!
>>> THE "JIMMY KIMMEL LIVE"
CONCERT SERIES SPONSORED BY BUD
LIGHT.
TO STREAM OFF AIR PERFORMANCES
AND OTHER MUSIC VIDEOS, GO TO
JIMMYKIMMELLIVE.COM.
>>> CAN'T GET ENOUGH KIMMEL?
FIND HIGHLIGHTS AND MORE AT
ABC.COM.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S THAT TIME OF YEAR AGAIN.
TIME FOR CITI PRICE REWIND.
BECAUSE YOUR DAUGHTER REALLY
WANTS THAT PINK CASTLE THING.
AND YOU REALLY DON'T WANT
TO PAY MORE THAN YOU HAVE TO.
ONLY CITI PRICE REWIND
AUTOMATICALLY SEARCHES
FOR THE LOWEST PRICE.
AND IF IT FINDS ONE, YOU GET
REFUNDED THE DIFFERENCE.
JUST USE YOUR CITI CARD
AND REGISTER YOUR PURCHASE
ONLINE.
HAVE A SUPER SPARKLY DAY!
OK.
[ Male Announcer ] NOW ALL
YOU NEED IS A MAGIC CARRIAGE.
CITI PRICE REWIND.
START SAVING
AT CITI.COM/PRICEREWIND.
CRAFTED WITH A TOUCH
OF WHISKY, WINE, AND BEER
BY HIGHLY SKILLED CHEFS.
YEP, THIS IS REAL.
DOUBLE BARREL WHISKY SIRLOINS
AND NEW NAPA CHICKEN
& PORTOBELLOS,
STARTING AT $9.99.
SEE YOU TOMORROW.
>> Jimm
>> Jimmy: STILL TO COME, DAN
DEACON IS HERE.
UP NEXT, HIS SHOW "HAPPY
ENDINGS" WAS JUST NAMED ONE OF
THE TOP TEN SHOWS OF 2012, AIRS
TUESDAY NIGHTS AT 9:00 HERE ON
ABC, PLEASE SAY HELLO TO ZACHARY
KNIGHTON.
>> HOW'S IT GOING?
>> Jimmy: DOING WELL.
HOW YOU DOING?
>> I'M DOING WELL.
>> Jimmy: WHERE ARE YOU FROM
ORIGINALLY?
>> I'M FROM VIRGINIA ORIGINALLY.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Jimmy: THEY'RE JUST VIRGINS.
DID YOU START ACTING THERE?
>> I DID.
I WENT TO AN ACTING HIGH SCHOOL
THERE.
I WENT TO COLLEGE IN VIRGINIA
AND ACTUALLY GOT SOME OF MY
FIRST JOBS IN VIRGINIA.
>> Jimmy: YOU GOT ACTING JOBS IN
VIRGINIA.
>> I DID.
MY FIRST ACTING JOB WAS THIS
MOVIE THAT NOBODY HAS SEEN
CALLED "CHERRY FALLS," WHICH IS
THIS HORROR FILM STARRING JAY
MOHR AND MICHAEL BEAN.
AND FUNNY ENOUGH, BACK IN THOSE
DAYS, YOU HAD THE RESUME ON THE
BACK OF YOUR PICTURE.
>> Jimmy: THEY DON'T DO THAT
ANYMORE?
>> I DON'T THINK THEY DO THAT.
BUT THEY SENT -- THEY WERE
LOOKING FOR SOMEBODY TO PLAY A
YOUNG MICHAEL BEAN IN A
FLASHBACK.
SO THEY SENT OUR HEAD SHOTS IN,
ME AND MY ROOMMATE'S HEAD SHOTS
IN, AND THEY ACTUALLY MIXED UP
THE RESUMES.
SO THEY THOUGHT THEY WERE
CASTING MY FRIEND, BUT THEY
THOUGHT HIS NAME WAS ZACHARY
KNIGHTON.
SO I GET A PHONE CALL, I GET MY
FIRST MOVIE.
IT'S LIKE, YOU KNOW, I'M 17
YEARS OLD, IT'S THE BIGGEST
PHONE CALL I'VE EVER GOTTEN IN
MY LIFE, AND I GET THE CALL, I
GOT THE JOB, I SHOW UP TO SET, I
GET MY HAIRCUT, I GET THE MAKEUP
DONE, I GET WARDROBE, AND I'M
SITTING IN MY TRAILER, I'M SO
NERVOUS, I'M WAITING AROUND AND
I GET THIS KNOCK AT THE DOOR.
AND THEY GO, HEY, WE HAVE SOME
BAD NEWS.
YOU'RE NOT THE GUY THAT WE
THOUGHT WE WERE CASTING.
AND AT THE SAME TIME, I GET THE
PHONE CALL -- I GET THE KNOCK AT
THE DOOR, I GET A PHONE CALL
FROM MY ROOMMATE AND FRIEND,
HEY, MAN, I JUST GOT MY FIRST
PART IN THIS MOVIE "CHERRY
FALLS"!
>> Jimmy: OH NO.
>> THEY MIX IT UP, BUT --
>> Jimmy: THEY FIRED YOU?
>> THEY FIRED ME ON THE SPOT.
THEY TOLD ME I DIDN'T HAVE A
JOB.
I WAS DISTRAUGHT, I WAS
HEARTBROKEN.
AND I GET A PHONE CALL ABOUT
3:00 IN THE MORNING.
WE FEEL TERRIBLE ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED.
WE WANT YOU TO DO THE MOVIE.
SO WE WROTE A PART, WE CREATED A
PART FOR YOU IN THE MOVIE.
>> Jimmy: WOW.
THAT'S NICE.
EXCEPT FOR THE CALLING YOU AT
3:00 PART.
THAT SEEMS UNNECESSARY.
>> I DIDN'T CARE.
INCIDENTALLY, IT ENDED UP BEING
A MUCH BETTER PART BECAUSE MY
ROOMMATE, THE YOUNG MICHAEL
BEAN, WAS A RAPIST IN THE MOVIE.
AND I ENDED UP PLAYING THIS
CRAZY GUY CLAIMING TO BE THE
SERIAL KILLER.
>> Jimmy: YOU DIDN'T HAVE TO BE
A RAPIST.
THAT'S NICE.
>> NO.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> Jimmy: YOU WERE LIVING WITH A
RAPIST, WHICH IS NOT THAT GOOD
EITHER.
AND NOW YOU LIVE HERE IN LOS
ANGELES, I WOULD ASSUME?
>> YES.
I LIVE IN TOPANGA.
WHICH IS SORT OF A CANYON OFF
MALIBU.
>> Jimmy: YEAH, THAT'S LIKE A
WEIRD PLACE, ISN'T IT?
>> IT'S KIND OF THIS HIPPIE
NEIGHBORHOOD.
I BELIEVE THE MANSON FAMILY GOT
THEIR START THERE.
>> Jimmy: YEAH.
>> A NICE PLACE TO LIVE.
I LOVE IT BECAUSE WE SORT OF,
YOU KNOW, I HAVE A FAMILY, A
WIFE.
>> Jimmy: A MANSON FAMILY?
>> NO.
NO.
>> Jimmy: A REGULAR FAMILY.
>> A REGULAR HUMAN FAMILY.
I LOVE IT BECAUSE I GET TO HAVE
CHICKENS.
>> Jimmy: I'VE BEEN WANTING TO
GET CHICKENS IN MY BACKYARD.
>> I HAVE CHICKENS.
>> Jimmy: HOW DO YOU LIKE HAVING
CHICKENS?
IS IT ALL IT'S CRACKED UP TO BE?
I REALLY DO, I'M NOT KIDDING.
I WANT TO GET CHICKENS IN MY
BACKYARD.
>> IT WAS AMAZING UP UNTIL LAST
WEEK WHEN MY CHICKENS MET A
TERRIBLE END.
>> Jimmy: OH NO.
>> I LEFT IN THE MORNING.
I WAS GOING ON SORT OF A DAY
WITH SOME OF MY BROS AND I
CALLED HOME TO CHECK UP ON
THINGS, AND MY FATHER-IN-LAW
ANSWERED THE CALL.
HE'S THIS 72-YEAR-OLD AMAZING
INSANE VIETNAMESE MAN AND HE
SAID, OH, I'M VERY UPSET.
I'M VERY UPSET.
I SAID WHAT'S THE MATTER, HIP?
>> Jimmy: WHAT?
>> HIPDANG IS HIS NAME.
HE SAYS I'M VERY UPSET.
I SAID WHAT'S THE MATTER?
HE SAID THE CHICKENS ARE GONE.
AND SO I SAID, WHAT'S WRONG?
HE SAID SOME ANIMAL TOOK THE
CHICKENS.
SO I GET MY WIFE ON THE PHONE.
THE WIFE GETS ON THE PHONE.
SHE GOES DAD!
SHE WAS TRYING TO BASICALLY HIDE
THE FACT THAT THE CHICKENS HAD
BEEN -- THE CHICKEN COOP HAD
BEEN RAIDED BY THESE RACCOONS OR
SOMETHING, SOME KIND OF ANIMAL,
AND WAS TRYING TO PATCH UP THE
COOP AND GET NEW CHICKENS SO I
WOULD NEVER KNOW.
WHICH IS VERY SWEET.
>> Jimmy: IS THIS A SITCOM?
>> PRETTY MUCH.
AND SHE HATES CHICKENS, BY THE
WAY, SO IT WAS VERY SWEET THAT
SHE WAS DOING THIS.
>> Jimmy: THAT IS A SACRIFICE
FOR HER TO MAKE.
DID SHE NOT THINK YOU WOULD
RECOGNIZE YOUR OWN CHICKENS?
>> THAT'S THE THING.
SHE GOT CHICKS.
THEY'RE BABIES.
>> Jimmy: THERE'S A TIME MACHINE
IN THE COOP.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> SO I WAS VERY UPSET.
I CAME HOME AND MY FATHER-IN-LAW
AND I DECIDED THAT WE WERE GOING
TO DO A RAID.
WE WERE GOING TO STAKE OUT THE
COOP AND GET THESE RACCOONS.
NOT KILL THEM OR ANYTHING.
CATCH THEM AND RELEASE THEM.
SO WE ACTUALLY DID THAT LAST
NIGHT.
>> Jimmy: YOU GOT THEM?
>> NO, NO.
WE DIDN'T GET THEM.
>> Jimmy: WHAT HAPPENED?
>> WE STAKED OUT THE COOP FOR
ABOUT 45 MINUTES, AND THEN IT
STARTED RAINING.
>> Jimmy: HOLD ON FOR A SECOND.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN WHEN YOU STAKED
OUT?
WAITING IN THE CAR OUTSIDE
SMOKING?
WHY ARE YOU STAKING OUT -- WHAT
ARE YOU GOING TO DO WHEN THE
RACCOONS SHOW UP?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
I WAS HOPING THAT HIPDANG WOULD
HAVE ALL THE ANSWERS.
[ LAUGHTER ]
WE GOT ALL GEARED UP.
>> Jimmy: YOUR FATHER-IN-LAW IS
HERE.
>> YEAH, HE'S HERE.
>> Jimmy: WHAT EXACTLY WERE YOU
GUYS GOING TO DO IF THE RACCOON
SHOWED UP?
>> SAY IT AGAIN, BILLY?
>> Jimmy: I'M NOT BILLY.
I'M JIMMY.
HOW WOULD YOU HAVE CAPTURED THE
RACCOONS?
>> WE THINK THEY WILL COME BACK
AGAIN.
SO WE WILL WAIT TO COME IN AND
WE SHOOT THEM.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Jimmy: DO YOU HAVE A GUN?
>> A BB GUN.
>> Jimmy: DO YOU HAVE A GUN TO
SHOOT THEM WITH?
>> BB GUN.
>> Jimmy: OH, A BB GUN.
THIS IS A LITTLE DARKER THAN YOU
HAD INITIALLY -- SO YOU'RE GOING
SHOOT THEM WITH THE BB GUN AND
THEN YOU FIGURED YOU WOULD LEARN
THEIR LESSON.
>> BUT THEY DON'T COME.
>> Jimmy: THEY DIDN'T COME.
WILL YOU BE WAITING FOR THEM
TONIGHT?
>> YEAH.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> I ACTUALLY BROUGHT A PICTURE
OF HIP AND I ON OUR MISSION LAST
NIGHT.
>> Jimmy: WHAT IS THIS?
WHAT IS GOING ON?
[ APPLAUSE ]
IT'S GOING TO BE A GREAT MOVIE.
>> THIS IS AN OLD -- KIND OF A
LOT OF OLD HIPPIES LIVE IN THIS
NEIGHBORHOOD.
SO I STARTED TO THINK -- I GOT
THIS VEIETNAMESE MAN IN CAM MOE
AND I'M THINKING I'M GOING TO
SEND SOME POOR BASTARD INTO A
FLASH BACK.
WE CALLED IT OFF.
WE WERE COLD AND WET AND I
WANTED TO WATCH TV.
MY HUNTING DAYS ARE OVER.
>> THIS IS QUITE A TALE.
THE SHOW IS VERY FUNNY, "HAPPY
ENDINGS."
NOT AS FUNNY AS YOUR REAL LIFE.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Jimmy: DID YOUR FATHER-IN-LAW
WATCH THE SHOW?
>> YEAH, HE WATCHES.
YOU WATCH THE SHOW, RIGHT?
>> Jimmy: DO YOU WATCH "HAPPY
ENDINGS"?
>> YEAH.
>> Jimmy: DO YOU LIKE IT?
>> I LOVE IT.
>> Jimmy: YOU LOVE IT.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT NIGHT IT'S ON?
>> TUESDAY.
>> Jimmy: THAT IS ABSOLUTELY
RIGHT.
IT IS ON TUESDAY NIGHTS AT 9:00
HERE ON ABC.
ZACHARY KNIGHTON AND HIS
FATHER-IN-LAW HIP, EVERYBODY.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH DAN
DEACON.
>> Dicky: THE "JIMMY KIMMEL
LIVE" CONCERT SERIES SPONSORED
BY BUD LIGHT.
>> Jimmy: THIS IS HIS LATEST
ALBUM, IT'S CALLED "AMERICA."
MAKING HIS NETWORK TELEVISION
DEBUT, DAN DEACON.
♪