HIT 80 MILES IN CATALINA.
NO TSUNAMI WARNING HAS BEEN
ISSUED.
PEOPLE SAY THE QUAKE SHOOK THEM
OUT OF BED.
>> Eric: AS WE SAID A LITTLE
FROST OUT THERE TH MORNING.
YOU HAD TO SCRAPE THE
WINDSHIELD.
>> I DID HAVE A SCRAPE THE WIND
SHIELD.
TEMPERATURES A LITTLE COOLER AND
MOISTURE IN THE AIR.
YOU CAN SEE SHOWING UP ON LIVE
DOPPLER 7-HD.
IT'S NOT MAKING IT TO THE GROUND
RIGHT NOW BUT POSSIBILITY OF
LIGHT RAIN.
YOU CAN SEE THIS ARCING NATURE
IN THE RADAR IT MEANS THE RADAR
IS SHOOTING UP INTO THE CLOUDS.
IT'S JUST TOPPING OFF THE
CLOUDS.
THAT IS GOOD NEWS.
WE HAVE CHANCE A LIGHT RAIN.
CLOSER YOU ARE TO THE OCEAN THE
MORE LIKELY YOU WILL GET LIGHT
RAIN.
WE WILL BE DEALING WITH COOL
CONDITIONS.
49 WILL BE THE WARMEST INLAND.
>> GOOD MORNING.
JUST ROAD WORK RIGHT NOW.
SOUTHBOUND GOLDEN GATE BRIDGE ON
THE NORTHERN PORTIONS OF THE
SPAN, DOWN TO ONE LANE FOR
HUNDRED FEET AND THEN BACK TO
TWO.
SLOW TRAFFIC DUE TO SOUTHERN
MARIN.
THIS IS PAST LUKAS VALLEY RESIDE
AND VERY LIGHT.
EASTBOUND CLOSED AT LEVY RIDGE
DUE ROAD WORK THERE AND THERE IS
A DETOUR IN PLACE.
>> Eric: EMPLOYEES AT A FIRE IN
FREMONT WILL LEARN TODAY HOW THE
BUSINESS PLANS TO GET GOING
AGAIN.
A FAST-MOVING FIRE GUTTED C AND
H ENTERPRISES, A MEDICAL
FABRICATION PLANT.
AMY HOLLYFIELD SHOWS US WHAT IS
LEFT TODAY.
>> Reporter: FIREFIGHTERS WILL
BE TRYING TO FIGURE OUT THE
CAUSED TO.
TAKE A LOOK BEHIND ME.
THE BUILDING IS NOT SAFE.
THEY HAVE SECURED IT TO KEEP
PEOPLE FROM GETTING INSIDE.
THEY ARE WAITING UNTIL ENGINEERS
CAN GO INSIDE AND GIVE THE ALL
CLEAR THAT IT IS SAFE IN THERE.
THIS CAUGHT FIRE IN FREMONT JUST
BEFORE 2:00 YESTERDAY AFTERNOON.
FIREFIGHTERS SAY THE FIRE WAS
INTENSE, THAT THE ROOF COLLAPSED
AND THEY WEREN'T ABLE TO GO
INSIDE.
THERE WERE ABOUT 60 EMPLOYEES
INSIDE THE BUILDING WHEN THE
FIRE STARTED, ONE PERSON EVEN
TRIED TO PUT OUT THE FIRE.
>> I TRIED TO DO SOMETHING BUT
IT JUST CAUGHT ON TOO FAST.
IT WAS PRETTY DEVASTATING.
>> THIS FIRE WAS FULLY INVOLVED
WHEN WE ARRIVED.
>> Reporter: NO ONE WAS
LITERATURE.
EVERYONE GOT OUT OKAY.
FIREFIGHTERS DID EVACUATE A FEW
BUILDINGS AROUND C AND H AS A
PRECAUTION BUT THEY CUT IT TO
THIS BUILDING.
A FIREWALL PLAYED A BIG ROLE
FROM KEEPING IT SPREADING.
DIRECTOR OF OPERATIONS AT THE
COMPANY SAYS THEY HAVE GOOD
INSURANCE AND IT WILL COVER THE
LOST WAGES FOR EMPLOYEES.
AMY HOLLYFIELD, "ABC 7 NEWS".
>> Kristen: THERE WILL BE EXTRA
SECURITY AT TWO SOUTH BAY
SCHOOLS WHEN THEY REOPEN ON TH
MORNING.
THEY WILL BE ON CAMPUS AT MONTE
VISTA HIGH SCHOOL AND CUPERTINO
HIGH SCHOOL AFTER A BOMB THREAT.
GRAFFITI SCRAWLED ON A WALL A
DIFFERENT SCHOOL CLAIMED THERE
WAS BOMB AT MONTEVISTA AND
THREATENED TO KILL A TEACHER
THERE.
NO DEVICE WAS FOUND AFTER
COMPLETE SWEEP.
AUTHORITIES SAY THEY ARE MAKING
SURE THAT TEACHER REMAINS UNDER
PROTECTION.
>> Eric: WOMAN ACCUSED OF
ABANDONING HER NEWBORN BABY IS
EXPECTED TO BE ARRAIGNED TODAY
ON CHARGES OF CHILD CRUELTY.
A MAN FOUND THE BABY LYING IN
THE BAYVIEW DISTRICT.
SHE IDENTIFIED AS 39-YEAR-OLD
NANEKKA NASH.
DOCTORS SAY THEY FOUND TRACES OF
COCAINE IN THE NEWBORN'S SYSTEM.
>> PG&E IS RUSHING TO INSPECT
MORE THAN 1500 PIECES OF UNDER
GROUND ELECTRICAL EQUIPMENT IN
THE BAY AREA FOR POSSIBLE SAFETY
HAZARDS.
THIS COMES AFTER REQUIRED
INSPECTIONS INTENDED TO HEAD OFF
DISASTROUS ACCIDENTS MAY NOT
HAVE ACTUALLY BEEN PERFORMED.
PG&E HAS EXPERIENCED EXPLOSIONS
AND FIRES IN UNDER GROUND VAULTS
IN SAN FRANCISCO INCLUDING ONE
IN UNION SQUARE IN 2005 THAT
SENT A MANHOLE COVER INTO THE
AIR AND INJURED A PASSERBY.
THEY SUSPENDED EMPLOYEES WHEN
THEY CLAIMED TO CHECK EQUIPMENT
WHEN THEY DID NOT.
>> A MAN IS SCHEDULED ON TO BE
IN COURT TODAY.
STEVEN REID DIED AT MONDAY AT A
HOSPITAL AFTER HE AND HIS
GIRLFRIEND WERE FOUND TIED UP IN
THE MIDDLE OF THE STREET.
POLICE BELIEVE THEY WERE VICTIMS
OF A BRUTAL HOME INVASIONS BY A
GROUP OF ACQUAINT AND IN THE VIS
IT STATION VALLEY NEIGHBORHOOD.
ONE IS SUSPECTED TO BE ARRAIGNED
AND THREE SUSPECTINGS WHO ARE
WOMAN ARE TO BE AT THE HEARING.
>> A ROBBERS HIT PHARMACIES IN
DUBLIN AND PLEASANTON.
THIS MAP SHOWS THE FOUR STORES
THE MEN TARGETED YESTERDAY.
IN EACH CASE THE ROBBER HANDED
OVER A NOTE DEMANDING
PRESCRIPTION DRUGS AND CLAIMING
TO BE ARMED.
THEY THINK TWO OR MORE PEOPLE
ARE WORKING AS A TEAM.
>> Eric: A WOMAN IS RECOVERING
AFTER FALLING INTO THE BAY OFF
THE EMBARCADERO.
IT HAPPENED BETWEEN WATERFRONT
RESTAURANT AND FERRY BUILDING.
SHE WAS QUICKLY RESCUED AND SHE
APPEAR TO BE INTOXICATED.
THE WOMAN WAS TAKEN TO THE
HOSPITAL AS A PRECAUTION.
>> Kristen: PORTLAND MALL WHERE
GUNMAN INCLUDING THREE LIVES
INCLUDING HIS OWN.
A CANDLELIGHT VIGIL IS SET FOR
TONIGHT.
POLICE ARE TRYING TO FIND OUT
22-YEAR-OLD JAKE ROCKETS WALKED
INTO THE TOWN CENTER ON TUESDAY
WEARING A HOCKEY MASK AND
CAMOUFLAGED CLOTHING AND OPENED
FIRE.
A TEENAGE GIRL WAS ALSO BOUNDED.
HIS EX-GIRLFRIEND SAID HE QUIT
HIS JOB AND SOLD EVERYTHING DAYS
BEFORE THE ATTACK BUT THERE IS
STILL NO CLEAR MOTIVE.
>> Eric: SUSAN RICE WITHDREW HER
NAME FOR CONSIDERATION FOR
CONSIDERATION AS NEXT SECRETARY
OF STATE.
SHE CAME UNDER CRITICAL ANALYSIS
AFTER A DEADLY ATTACK IN
BENGHAZI.
KATIE MARZULLO WILL JOIN US WHO
IS ELSE IS BEING CONSIDERED FOR
THE JOB AND HOW IT COULD IMPACT
OTHER KEY POSITIONS.
>> YOU TALK ABOUT HOW FROSTY TI
IT WAS THIS MORNING.
DID YOU HAVE TO DO SCRAPING OF
THE WINDSHIELD.
>> I USED THE DID HE FROS
TERRIFY BUT WHEN YOU BECOME A
CALIFORNIAN YOU DON'T HAVE AN
ICE SCRAPER ANYMORE, MIKE.
>> YOUR CREDIT CARD.
I ACTUALLY HAVE ONE WHEN WE CAME
FROM MINNESOTA.
YOU NEVER KNOW WHEN YOU MIGHT
NEED IT.
IT MIGHT BE A GOOD GOOD
CHRISTMAS PRESENT.
RADAR SATELLITE, YOU CAN SEE A
LIGHT BLUE, GREEN, SO FAR
NOTHING REACHING THE GROUND.
SIART JUST TOO DRY AND LET'S
TALK ABOUT HOW COMB IT IS.
INTERIOR EAST BAY VALLEYS,
HOLLISTER, SALINAS VALLEY, UNDER
A FROST VALLEY WHERE THE LOWS
ARE AROUND 30-34.
DEFINITELY GOING TO BE DIFFICULT
TO SEE OUT OF THE CAR EARLIER IF
YOU CAN'T GET OUT AND SCRAPE IT.
TEMPERATURE DROPPED DOWN TO 29.
HERE IS A LOOK AT SOME OF THE
TEMPERATURES.
FOR ABOUT 34 IN SANTA ROSA.
35 IN NAPA.
32 IN LIVERMORE FOR THE COOL
SPOT.
36 IN REDWOOD CITY TO ABOUT 43
IN OAKLAND, 44 IN SAN FRANCISCO
AND AROUND 40 IN SAN JOSE.
AS WE HEAD THROUGHOUT THE DAY
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE A SLIGHT
CHANCE OF SLIGHT RAIN NEAR THE
COAST.
TEMPERATURES IN THE 40s TO LOW
50s.
WE'LL GET A BETTER CHANCE OF
RAIN TOMORROW.
SCATTERED RAIN AROUND SUNDAY BUT
NOTICE THE TEMPERATURES WILL
START TO CLIMB AS WE HEAD
THROUGH THE WEEKEND.
>>> DRY ROADS THIS MORNING.
THAT IS GOOD NEWS FOR YOUR
FRIDAY MORNING COMMUTE.
FIRST LOOK AT THE BAY BRIDGE
TOLL PLAZA, FEW HEADLIGHTS
PASSING THROUGH.
NO ISSUES ON THE UPPER DECK
MAKING YOUR WAY INTO SAN
FRANCISCO.
SAN MATEO BRIDGE THIS MORNING,
TAILLIGHTS HEADED OVER TO
WESTBOUND IN SAN MATEO, FOSTER
CITY AREA, JUST A FEW TAILLIGHTS
AND BRAKE LIGHTS AT THE
HIGH-RISE, ABOUT 13-14 MINUTES
BETWEEN THE PENINSULA AND THE
EAST BAY.
NORTH 101, LOAD WORK, I SAW THIS
COMING IN.
MILL VALLEY TO LARKSPUR,
REPAVING PROJECT UNDERWAY UNTIL
6:00 A.M.
THREE RIGHT LANES UNTIL 9:00
A.M.
ONE LANE IS GETTING BY IN THE
EASTBOUND DIRECTION.
THEY ARE STRIPING THE ROADS, 880
BOTH DREBLGSZ FRUIT VAL AND
EMBARCADERO, EXPECT VARIOUS LANE
CLOSURES IN BOTH DIRECTIONS.
>> Kristen: LISTEN VERY CLOSELY,
CYBER CROOKS PREPARING TO FUNNEL
MONEY OUT OF YOUR BANK ACCOUNT.
WHAT YOU NEED TO DO TO PROTECT
YOURSELF.
>> AND NEW TWIST ON THE LOCKYER
SEX AND DRUG SCANDAL.
HER LATEST OVER THE REHAB AND
You disgust me.
Prove it.
Enough is enough.
d-CON baits are specially
formulated
to kill in one feeding.
Guaranteed.
D-CON.
Get out.
>> Eric: WELCOME BACK.
ONE OF BAY AREA'S POLITICAL
SCANNEDS OF 2012 HAS TAKEN A
MAJOR TURN.
I-TEAM HAS LEARNED THAT FORMER
SERVICE NADIA LOCKYER HAS
ALLOWED A RESTRAINING ORDER
AGAINST HER BOYFRIEND EXPIRE.
HER CAREER IMPLODED AFTER A
VIOLENT CONFRONTATION WITH HER
BOYFRIEND TEN MONTHS AGO.
THEY TALKED ABOUT THEIR METH USE
AND SEX TAPE.
HE SHE REMAINS IN DRUG REHAB AND
HER ATTORNEY MADE A STATEMENT.
>> NADIA WILL GO THROUGH
TREATMENT AND RECONSIDER HER
OPTIONS AND ONE OF OPTIONS WILL
BE, OF COURSE, TO CONTINUE TO
PURSUE THIS.
ANOTHER OPTION MAY BE TO LET
MATTERS LIE WHERE THEY ARE.
>> Eric: HER HUSBAND FILED FOR
DIVORCE IN JULY BUT NADIA'S
ATTORNEYS SAID THE DIVORCE IS ON
HOLD.
BILL LOCKYER IS PAYING FOR HER
STAY IN DRUG REHAB AND ALSO
BRINGING THEIR SON TO SEE HER ON
A REGULAR BASIS.
>> A MASSIVE CYBER ATTACK AND IT
COULD AFFECT YOUR BANK ACCOUNT.
THE PLAN INVOLVES DOZENS OF
BANKS.
LILIAN KIM HAS THE DETAILS YOU
NEED TO KNOW.
>> Reporter: WE WANTED TO INFORM
CONSUMERS.
JUST BE AWARE.
>> Reporter: MACK AFEE HAS BEEN
INVESTIGATING FOR MONTHS AND
THEY SAY THE EVIDENCE IS CLEAR.
HACKERS ARE PLANNING TO ATTACK
YOUR BANK ACCOUNT.
HE HAS SO FAR DETECTED HUNDREDS
OF COMPUTERS WITH SOPHISTICATED
MALWA WILL RE.
>> WHEN YOU TRY TO LOG INTO THE
FINANCIAL INSTITUTION, THAT IS
WHEN IT WILL ACTIVATE.
IT REREPLICATES ON A SERVER IN
RUSSIA.
ONCE THEY CLONE IT THEY TRY TO
LOG INTO THE BANK.
>> IT INVOLVES FUNNELING MONEY
OUT OF 30 BANKS.
HOPE IS THE FINANCIAL INDUSTRY
WAY OF DEALING WITH SEENER
THIEVES WILL MINIMIZE ANY LOSS.
CHIEF INVESTMENT OF MERK FUND.
>> UTILITY COMPANIES THAT DEAL
WITH I.T. AND FROM THAT POINT
THEY HAVE THE RESOURCES TO DEAL
WITH THESE ISSUES.
IT'S THE COST OF DOING BUSINESS.
>> HE SAYS THE PLAN LIKELY
INVOLVES TARGETING PEOPLE WITH
HIGH NET WORTH BUT ALL CUSTOMERS
ARE ADVISED TO MAKE SURE THE
ANTI-SOFTWARE IS WORKING THE WAY
IT IS SUPPOSED TO.
>> THE EVIDENCE REAL PERSONAL
FOR ATTACK, WE THINK THE
LIKELIHOOD IS HIGH.
>> Eric: 4:45.
OAKLAND AND SAN FRANCISCO POLICE
DEPARTMENTS, BOTH DEPTH WILL
HOLD GUN BUY-BACK PROGRAMS.
THEY WILL GET $200 CASH PER
WEAPON BUT THE LIMIT IS THREE.
IN OAKLAND THE BUY-BACK PROGRAM
WILL IT BE HELD AT ST. BEEN
DIGITS CHURCH, IN SAN FRANCISCO,
IT'S OMEGA'S BOYS CLUB.
WE HAVE MORE INFORMATION ON OUR
WEBSITE AT ABC7NEWS.COM, LOOK
UNDER "SEE IT ON TV".
>> Kristen: ONE OF HAYWARD'S
MOST FAMILIAR LAND MARKS NEEDS
REPAIRS AFTER DAMAGE DONE AFTER
A SERIES OF STORMS.
THEY WERE SIZING UP THE DAMAGES
TO ONE OF THE CHURCH'S BELL
TOWERS.
THEY SOAR HUNDRED FEET IN
DOWNTOWN HAYWARD.
IT CATS BACK HUNDRED YEARS AND
PARISH STARTED IN 1868.
THEY HAVE STARTED A FUND TO FIX
THE DAMAGE AND SHORE UP OTHER
PARTS OF THEIR AGING CHURCH.
WE HAVE ANOTHER SERIES OF STORMS
THAT WILL CAUSE SOME ADDITIONAL
CONCERN THERE.
>> Kristen: LET'S FIND OUT MIKE.
>> SEVERAL SYSTEMS ARE COMING
IN, BUT THEY ARE MOISTURE
STARVED THEY ARE NOT GOING TO BE
WHAT WE HAD LATELY.
ANY TIME WE HAVE STORMS COMING
FROM THE WEST NOT LIKE DUE WEST
WHERE WE HAVE THE DAMAGING
STORMS.
DRY SKY AS WE LOOK BACK FROM
VOLLMER PEAK AND INTO SAN
FRANCISCO.
YOU CAN SEE THE CLOUDS OUT THERE
BEING LIT FROM THE LIGHTS INTO
THE CITY THIS MORNING.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT LIVE
DOPPLER 7-HD.
YOU CAN SEE THE CLOUDS HAVEN'T
MADE IT OVER TO THE EAST BAY
VALLEYS.
THAT IS WHERE YOU WILL FIND YOUR
COOLEST TEMPERATURES.
ENCLOSE CLOUDS ARE ROAMING
ACROSS EVERYWHERE ELSE.
SO FAR NO RAIN MAKING IT TO THE
GROUND BUT THE DARKER GREEN YOU
SEE AUTO OVER THE OCEAN THAT
PROBABLY HAS A BETTER CHANCE OF
ACTUALLY REACHING THE GROUND.
THAT WILL BE THE CASE WITH THIS
STORM.
IT'S SHIFTING OVER THE OCEAN IT
HAS THAN OVER OUR NEIGHBORHOODS.
THEN THE MODELS CHANGED A LITTLE
BIT AND NOW THEY ARE BACK.
EAST BAY VALLEYS, EVERYWHERE YOU
SEE IN YELLOW THAT IS WHERE IT'S
GOING TO BE COLDER AND FROSTY
COLD UNTIL 8:00 THIS MORNING.
680, OUT 4 AND EVEN AROUND RODEO
AND PINOLE, RICHMOND, FROST.
TEMPERATURES IN THE 30s EXCEPT
FOR ANTIOCH.
CHECK OUT REDWOOD CITY, 36.
SAN JOSE AT 39.
LOW TO MID 40s OUT TO THE COAST.
TEMPERATURES IN THE 30s AROUND
THE MONTEREY BAY AND INLAND.
MONTEREY AT ABOUT 41 DEGREES.
TODAY'S RAIN IS BEST OVER THE
OCEAN.
WE'LL HAVE A BETTER CHANCE OF
SEEING RAIN TOMORROW AND IF YOU
DON'T GET ANY THEN, MORE CHANCES
TO INCLUDE YOU IN THE CROWD AS
WE HEAD THROUGH NEXT WEEK.
FAST MOVING COLD FRONT, IT HAS
LIMITED MOISTURE.
YOU CAN SEE BEHIND IT A BIT OF
BREAK DURING THE AFTERNOON AND
OVERNIGHT HOURS.
THIS STORM COMES IN FOR
SATURDAY.
ON THE LEFT SIDE OF YOUR SCREEN,
THAT IS FOR NEXT WEEK.
THE HIGH PRESSURE THAT IS WHAT
IS STEERING ALL THOSE STORMS
TOWARDS US.
THE BEST RAIN OVER THE OCEAN.
LET ME GET OUT OF WAY YOU CAN
SEE IT.
STRAY SHOWER UP AROUND NOON.
BY 7:00, CLOUDS ARE OPENING AND
YOU ARE NEEDING A HEAVY COAT AS
TEMPERATURES DROP INTO THE 40s
AND EVEN THE 30s.
SUN, WE DON'T SEE MUCH ON
SATURDAY.
CLOUDS ROLL IN EARLY IN THE
MORNING HOURS AND RAIN COMES IN
AROUND 11:00 AND THEN SCATTERED
LIGHT RAIN THROUGHOUT THE
AFTERNOON AND EVENING HOURS.
OVERNIGHT, IT BECOMES MORE OF A
DRIZZLE AND HEADING TOWARD
SUNDAY, SCATTERED WAVES VERY FAR
LIGHT RAIN.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT A TENTH TO A
QUARTER OF AN INCH TOTAL OUT OF
THOSE TWO SYSTEMS.
ANOTHER CHANCE ON MONDAY BUT
NOTICE THE TEMPERATURES ARE
STARTING TO HIT THE UPPER 50s TO
NEAR 60.
A LITTLE COOLER WITH NEXT CHANCE
OF RAIN TUESDAY AND WEDNESDAY.
>> PRETTY LIGHT, SAN JOSE,
NORTHBOUND 87, PAST THE PAVILION
HEADLIGHTS PASSING THROUGH THE
SCREEN.
JULIAN OFF-RAMP TO GET AN IDEA
WHERE WE ARE.
BACK TO THE BAY BRIDGE, STILL
VERY LIGHT AS YOU MAKE YOUR WAY
WESTBOUND.
NO PROBLEMS.
SOME ROAD WORK, AT WASHINGTON,
TWO RIGHT LANES AND THE OFF-RAMP
WASHINGTON OFF-RAMP JUST FOR A
FEW MINUTES UNTIL 5:00 THIS
MORNING.
DUMBARTON, ONE LANE GETTING BY
THERE AND NORTH 101 PENINSULA
FROM 92 TOWARDS THIRD, THREE
LEFT LANES, ROAD WORK UNTIL
6:00 A.M. THIS MORNING, YOU CAN
SEE SLOW TRAFFIC SENATORS AND
RED DOTS MOVING IN THAT
DIRECTION AND THAT WILL BE
PICKED UP AT 6:00 THIS MORNING.
>> TIME IS 4:50.
TWO POLICE OFFICERS IN MEXICO
HAVE BEEN ARRESTED FOR STEALING
EVIDENCE IN THE SITE WHERE
SINGER JENNI RIVERA'S PLANE
CRASHED.
THEY WERE FOUND AT THE OFFICER'S
HOMES.
LAST NIGHT A CAR CARRYING THE
REMAINS WAS GIVEN A POLICE
ESCORT THROUGH LONG BEACH.
DRUG ENFORCEMENT ADMINISTRATION
IS INVESTIGATING THE COMPANY
THAT OWNS THE LUXURY JET THAT
CRASHED KILLING THE POP STAR AND
SIX OTHERS ON SUNDAY.
THEY SAY THEY HAD TWO PLANES
SEIZED THIS YEAR BY FEDERAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT.
>> COMING UP, HOW IS YOUR BACK?
THE PEOPLE YOU PROBABLY DON'T
KNOW WHO WILL BE OFFERING YOU
PROTECTION DURING THE HOLIDAYS.
>> AND ARE YOU THINKING ABOUT
GOING ABOUT FOR
>>> BART PATRONS TOOK ADVANTAGE
IN THE EFFORT TO KEEP PEOPLE
SAFE.
THEY PROVIDED TREE ESCORTS FOR
PEOPLE WALKING TO THEIR CARS.
ESCORTS GAVE THEM AN EXTRA SENSE
OF SECURITY ESPECIALLY SINCE IT
GETS DARKER EARLIER THIS TIME OF
THE YEAR.
>> FOR THE HOLIDAYS, THEY DO IT
ANY WAY THEY CAN.
IT'S BETTER THAN BE SAFE AND
SORRY.
>> IF YOU ARE TEXTING AND NOT
PAYING ATTENTION YOU BECOME A
VICTIM OF A CRIME OF
OPPORTUNITY.
>>> BART POLICE POINTED OUT THEY
WALKING ESCORTS YEAR A ROUND.
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO IS ASK A BART
STATION AGENT.
>>> WE WANT TO THANK YOU TO MAKE
ABC7 SHARE YOUR HOLIDAY FOOD
DRIVE A GREAT SUCCESS.
YOU DONATED MORE THAN $22,000 TO
BAY AREA FOOD BANKS ON
WEDNESDAY.
THAT TRANSLATES TO FOOD FOR
70,000 PEOPLE.
OUR SHARE YOUR HOLIDAY FOOD
DRIVE CONTINUES THROUGH DECEMBER
31.
DONATE BY CALLING THE NUMBER ON
THE SCREEN OR GIVE $10 BY
TEXTING THE WORD FEED TO 80077.
LIKE US OR CLICK US DONATING
ONLINE.
SEVERAL WAYS TO GIVE.
WE ENCOURAGE YOU TO CHECK IT OUT
AT ABC7NEWS.COM.
>>> MIKE, MY ICE SCRAPER
DISAPPEAR EONS AGO.
>> SOMETIME HAD IT, ITS SMALL
ONE AND STUCK IT IN THE BACK OF
THE CAR.
IT'S NICE TO HAVE.
DEFINITELY FROSTY CONDITIONS,
GOOD MORNING.
LOOK AT THE HIGHS IN THE
AFTERNOON, ONLY IN THE 40s
INLAND, SOME LOWS 50s AS WE HEAD
AROUND THE BAY AND OUT TO THE
COAST.
REMEMBER WE HAVE A CHANCE OF
LIGHT RAIN AND EVEN A SCATTERED
LIGHT SHOWER DURING THE
AFTERNOON HOURS.
MOST OF THE MOISTURE IS MAKING
UP TO THE NORTH AND MAKING IT TO
THE GROUND.
IT IS HEADING TOWARDS TAHOE.
YOU WILL GET SNOW SHOWERS AND
BETTER CHANCE OF LIGHT SNOW ON
SUNDAY.
>>> NO CHAIN REQUIREMENTS RIGHT
NOW UP IN THE SIERRA EXCEPT FOR
HIGHWAY 88 BUT 50 AND 80 ARE
CLEAR.
WATCH THE CREWS ON THE GOLDEN
GATE BRIDGE, YOU SEE THE
FLASHING LIGHTS PICKING UP THOSE
CONES AND RECONFIGURING FOR YOUR
ROAD COMMUTE.
BAY BRIDGE, STILL LIGHT AND NO
PROBLEMS INTO SAN FRANCISCO.
EASTBOUND 4 REMAINS CLOSED DUE
TO LOAD WORK.
THEY HAVE A DETOUR IN PLACE.
MILL VALLEY TO LARKSPUR, YOU
MIGHT FIND SLOWING IN THE
NORTHBOUND DIRECTION.
>> NEW THIS MORNING, THE SENATE
TURNING ITS ATTENTION TO A $60
BILLION DISASTER AID PACKAGE FOR
SANDY VICTIMS.
THEY WILL DEBATE THE BILL ON
MONDAY.
REPUBLICANS ARE LOOKING AT A
SMALLER INITIAL PACKAGE TO COVER
IMMEDIATE NEEDS.
THEY ARE AWAITING FOR MORE
DETAILED EVIDENCE ON DAMAGES FOR
ADDITIONAL SPENDING.
MEANTIME, THE TEACHERS' UNION
ARE PLEDGING A BILLION DOLLARS
TO HELP REPAIR ROADS AND BRIDGES
>>> BLUE SHIELD IS PROPOSING
RAISING RATES AS MUCH AS 20% TO
INDIVIDUAL POLICYHOLDERS.
>> SHAME ON YOU!
>> PAST RATE HIKES HAVE
ATTRACTED MOLESTERS OUTSIDE
OFFICES IN SAN FRANCISCO.
UNDER THE PLAN, THE AVERAGE RATE
HIKE WOULD BE 12% BUT SOME COULD
SEE RATE INCREASES AS HIGH AS
20%.
CONSUMER GROUPS POINT TO THEIR
HUGE CASH RESERVE AND NEARLY 4
BYE AND SAY SOME OF THE MONEY
SHOULD BE USED TO OFF SET THE
RATE INCREASE.
THEY SAY THE MONEY IS NEEDED IT
CAN PAY ALL CLIMBS.
>> IF YOU GET UP EXTRA EARLY TO
GO FOR A RUN, NEW RESEARCH
SUGGESTS THAT BEST TIME MAY BE
THE AFTERNOON.
THEY USED MICE HOW EXERCISE
AFFECTS THE INTERNAL CLOCK.
THEY THOUGHT THEY WOULD SEE THE
BEST RESULTS FROM MORNING
EXERCISE BUT INSTEAD, MICE THAT
RAN LATER MAKE MORE PROTEINS.
>> IT'S 4:57.
A PAIR OF POWERFUL EARTHQUAKES
HIT OFF THE SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA
COAST.
WE ARE WATCHING FOR ANY REPORTS
OF DAMAGE.
>> AND 7 ON OFFER O YOUR SIDE
MICHAEL FINNEY WILL SHOW US
WHERE WE CAN GET THE COOLEST
GIFTS FOR UNDER $25.
>>> GOOD FRIDAY MONK, DECEMBER
14th, IT'S 5:00.
I'M KRISTEN SZE.
>> I'M ERIC THOMAS.
IT'S CHILLY AND FROSTY OUT THERE
FOR SOME OF US.
YOU MAY HAVE