MY SMILE NOW IS MORE LIKE THIS.
>> THE SUPERSMILE SYSTEM
WORKS IN MINUTES TO SAFELY
REMOVE EMBARRASSING STAINS
FROM YOUR TEETH.
PLUS, SUPERSMILE ACTUALLY
STRENGTHENS YOUR ENAMEL
WITH CALCIUM AND HELPS PREVENT
CAVITIES WITH FLUORIDE.
>> IT'S TAKING CARE OF MY TEETH.
MY GUMS FEEL HEALTHIER,
AND MY TEETH ARE NOTICEABLY
WHITER, AND I SAY THAT
WITH A BIG SMILE BECAUSE
IT REALLY DOES EXCITE ME.
IT MAKES ME FEEL GREAT.
>> TRAYS, STRIPS,
AND PROFESSIONAL WHITENING
CAN BE TIME-CONSUMING
AND EXPENSIVE.
SOME MAY EVEN BE DAMAGING
AND CAUSE SENSITIVITY.
AND THE RESULTS START
TO DIMINISH AS SOON AS YOU
START EATING AND DRINKING.
MANY WHITENING TOOTHPASTES
SCRAPE AWAY AT STAINS
WITH SILICA, A TYPE OF SAND,
THAT CAN DAMAGE YOUR ENAMEL.
AND TOOTH ENAMEL
DOESN'T GROW BACK.
BUT NOW, THERE'S A SAFE WAY
TO WHITEN YOUR TEETH,
AND IT'S GENTLE ENOUGH
TO USE EVERY DAY.
EAT, DRINK, EVEN SMOKE,
AND THE SUPERSMILE SYSTEM
WILL GET YOUR TEETH WHITER
AND KEEP THEM THAT WAY.
>> MY WHOLE ENTIRE MOUTH
JUST FEELS SO MUCH CLEANER
AND FRESHER, AND IT'S JUST--
HONESTLY, ALMOST LIKE
MY TEETH HAVE TAKEN A BATH.
>> SUPERSMILE IS CLINICALLY
SHOWN TO WHITEN TEETH
NEARLY FIVE SHADES IN 30 DAYS
EVEN IF YOU CONTINUE
TO SMOKE OR DRINK COFFEE,
TEA, OR RED WINE.
HERE'S THE SECRET.
SUPERSMILE HAS A DYNAMIC
PROPRIETARY INGREDIENT
NO ONE ELSE HAS.
IT'S CALLED "CALPROX,"
AND IT HAS CHANGED
THE SCIENCE OF TOOTH WHITENING.
NO MORE SCRATCHING
AND SCRAPING BECAUSE
SUPERSMILE WITH CALPROX
IS DESIGNED TO GENTLY
AND SAFELY DISSOLVE
AND LIFT STAINS AWAY FAST
EVERY TIME YOU BRUSH.
SUPERSMILE'S DUAL
STAIN FIGHTING ACTION
NOT ONLY LIFTS EMBARRASSING
STAINS GENTLY FROM THE SURFACE
OF YOUR TEETH,
IT EVEN FADES STUBBORN STAINS
DEEPER IN YOUR ENAMEL.
YOU'LL NEVER LOOK AT
TOOTH WHITENING
THE SAME WAY AGAIN.
>> SUPERSMILE IS THE ONLY
SYSTEM, THAT I AM AWARE OF,
THAT CAN HAVE SUCH RESULTS,
SUCH DRAMATIC RESULTS IN
SUCH A SHORT PERIOD OF TIME.
>> IT'S A GREAT PRODUCT
DEVELOPED WITH SCIENCE,
AND CONCERN FOR PATIENTS
BEHIND IT.
AND I THINK THAT'S WHAT MAKES
SUPERSMILE UNIQUE IN
THE INDUSTRY TODAY.
>> THE SUPERSMILE SYSTEM
WORKS ON NATURAL TEETH,
AND WILL EVEN WHITEN VENEERS,
CAPS, BONDING, CROWNS,
AND DENTURES BACK TO
THEIR WHITEST ORIGINAL SHADE.
IN FACT, 100% OF CLINICAL STUDY
PARTICIPANTS SAW RESULTS
WITH SUPERSMILE.
>> YOU SEE THE RESULTS
REALLY QUICKLY.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO WAIT
TWO WEEKS OR A MONTH
TO SEE THE CHANGES.
>> I'VE SEEN THOSE
HARD TO REACH TEETH GET WHITER
AND I FEEL MYSELF SMILING
BECAUSE OF IT.
>> SUPERSMILE HAS BEEN
AWARDED TOP HONORS BY
THE BEAUTY INDUSTRY INCLUDING
"BEST WHITENING TOOTHPASTE"
AND "BEST AT-HOME
WHITENING INNOVATION."
MAGAZINES, NEWSPAPERS,
BEAUTY BLOGS, THE MEDIA
CAN'T STOP TALKING
ABOUT SUPERSMILE.
LUCKY SAYS, "THIS STUFF
REALLY WORKS."
"YOU'LL GET A WOW RESULT,"
PROMISES IN STYLE WEDDINGS.
HARPER'S BAZAAR RAVES,
"SUPERSMILE WILL GIVE YOU
YOUR WHITEST POSSIBLE SMILE
WITHOUT SENSITIVITY."
AND USA TODAY SAYS,
"YOU'LL LOOK LIKE A STAR."
>> THERE'S DEFINITELY A LOT
OF BUZZ WITH SUPERSMILE.
IT'S REALLY THE GO-TO BRAND
IF YOU WANT GREAT LOOKING TEETH,
AND A BEAUTIFUL SMILE.
>> THE PEOPLE WHO READ
NEW BEAUTY MAGAZINE ARE
VERY INTERESTED IN BEAUTY
AND IN THEIR APPEARANCE.
WHAT DR. SMIGEL
AND SUPERSMILE HAVE DONE
IS THEY HAVE ENABLED
EVERYDAY PEOPLE TO HAVE
CELEBRITY SMILES.
>> SUPERSMILE WAS CREATED
BY DR. IRWIN SMIGEL, THE FATHER
OF AESTHETIC DENTISTRY,
AND THE ONLY DENTIST
THE SMITHSONIAN
NATIONAL MUSEUM OF DENTISTRY
HAS HONORED WITH A PERMANENT
EXHIBIT DEDICATED TO HIS
COUNTLESS ACHIEVEMENTS
INCLUDING THE INVENTION
OF TOOTH BONDING.
TOP CELEBRITIES HAVE FLOCKED
TO DR. SMIGEL'S
MADISON AVENUE OFFICE.
THEY KNOW THAT
IF YOU WANT THE BEST
HE'S THE MAN TO SEE.
>> WHEN YOU SMILE AND THAT
SMILE IS REALLY BRIGHT
THEY'RE LOOKING, THEY SAY,
"WOW, MY TEETH AREN'T
THAT WHITE.
HOW DO I GET 'EM LIKE THAT?"
WELL, SUPERSMILE, BABY.
>> COMING UP,
SEE PEOPLE JUST LIKE YOU
TRY THE SUPERSMILE SYSTEM
WHICH INCLUDES
DR. SMIGEL'S REVOLUTIONARY
PROFESSIONAL ACTIVATING RODS
FOR THE VERY FIRST TIME.
AND BE BLOWN AWAY
BY THE RESULTS
THEY GET IN JUST SIX MINUTES.
>> THEY ARE BETTER.
>> THAT'S CRAZY.
FIVE TO ONE, A ONE!
>> A SHADE FOUR,
TO ALL THE WAY
TO NUMBER ONE.
>> SEVEN TO A TWO.
>> I JUMPED FIVE SHADES
LIGHTER ACTUALLY.
>> ELEVEN TO A FOUR.
>> OVER FOUR MILLION PEOPLE
HAVE BRUSHED WITH
SUPERSMILE ALREADY,
NOW IT'S YOUR TURN.
TO FIND OUT MORE,
LET'S JOIN TELEVISION HOST,
AND LONGTIME SUPERSMILE USER,
LISA MASON.
>> DR. SMIGEL TELLS US
THAT WHATEVER WILL STAIN
A WHITE SHIRT WILL
STAIN YOUR TEETH.
LIKE COFFEE, CHOCOLATE,
OR RED WINE.
WHEN IT COMES TO WHITENING
YOUR TEETH, MOST PRODUCTS
LIKE TRAYS, STRIPS, OR
TREATMENTS YOU GET AT
THE DENTIST ARE USED
OCCASIONALLY AND WHEN YOU STOP
USING THEM ANY WHITENESS
AND BRIGHTNESS YOU MAY HAVE
SEEN BEGINS TO FADE.
THE STAINS START TO BUILD UP
AGAIN UNTIL YOU WHITEN AGAIN.
THIS CYCLE OF WHITENING,
FADING, AND WHITENING AGAIN
CAN ACTUALLY HURT YOUR TEETH
BY OVER-BLEACHING,
DAMAGING YOUR ENAMEL
AND CAUSING SENSITIVITY.
NOW, YOU CAN BREAK OUT OF THAT
HARMFUL CYCLE BECAUSE
SUPERSMILE'S SPECIAL INGREDIENT,
CALPROX, WHITENS SAFELY
BY GENTLY LIFTING STAINS AWAY
EVERY TIME YOU BRUSH.
SUPERSMILE DOES IT ALL.
IT STRENGTHENS ENAMEL,
CONTAINS FLUORIDE, REPLACES
YOUR REGULAR TOOTHPASTE,
AND TAKES JUST MINUTES A DAY.
AND IT'S THE ONLY WHITENING
SYSTEM WITH CALPROX.
JUST RINSE AND BRUSH,
AND YOU'RE ON YOUR WAY TO
A WIDER, BRIGHTER SMILE.
>> I DRINK COFFEE.
I SMOKE CIGARETTES.
I DRINK A LOT OF RED WINE,
BUT I BELIEVE IN THE PRODUCT
SO COMPLETELY, AND I JUST--
I CAN'T USE ANYTHING
BUT SUPERSMILE.
>> I STARTED USING STRIPS,
BUT THE THING ABOUT STRIPS
IS THAT THEY DIDN'T WHITEN
THE BACK OF MY TEETH.
SUPERSMILE HAS MADE MY SMILE
SO MUCH BRIGHTER, SO MUCH
SHINIER, SO MUCH WHITER,
AND SO MUCH HEALTHIER.
>> BY USING SUPERSMILE EVERY
DAY I DON'T HAVE TO WORRY
ABOUT STAINS ACCUMULATING
ON MY TEETH BECAUSE I KNOW
THAT I'M GOING TO BE USING
THE PRODUCTS AGAIN,
AND RE-WHITENING MY TEETH
EVERY SINGLE DAY.
>> RECENTLY, IN SANTA MONICA,
CALIFORNIA A GROUP OF LUCKY
PEOPLE TRIED THE SAME
SUPERSMILE SYSTEM YOU'RE
GETTING AT HOME.
THEY STARTED WITH
THE PROFESSIONAL ACTIVATING RODS
AND EXPERIENCED SOMETHING
WE CALLED, "SIX MINUTES
TO A SUPERSMILE."
>> SO, TAKE A LOOK AT
YOUR BEFORE SMILE.
>> OKAY.
>> AND SAY "GOODBYE" TO IT.
>> GOODBYE.
>> WE STARTED BY TAKING
EVERYBODY'S CURRENT TOOTH SHADE
WITH THE SUPERSMILE SHADE GUIDE.
>> YOU ARE ABOUT A 12.
>> A FOUR.
>> EIGHT.
>> THEN WE HAD EVERYONE
PREP AND PRIME THEIR TEETH WITH
THE PROFESSIONAL ACTIVATING RODS
USED ONCE A WEEK WITH
THE SUPERSMILE SYSTEM.
>> THE RODS WERE GREAT
AND IT WAS REALLY EASY TO USE.
>> WE BRUSH WITH THE SUPERSMILE
TOOTHPASTE AND ACCELERATOR.
RINSE WITH THE SUPERSMILE
PRE-RINSE THEN REPEAT IT.
AND THAT'S IT, JUST SIX MINUTES.
LET'S CHECK THE SHADE GUIDE
TO SEE RESULTS.
>> YOU'RE LIKE A NUMBER TWO,
YOU HAVE TO LOOK IN THE MIRROR.
>> WHAT?
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT,
THAT'S INCREDIBLE.
I WENT FROM A SEVEN TO A TWO.
>> I THINK SHE'S LIKE
A NUMBER TWO.
>> OH, I FEEL LIKE I WANT
TO SMILE ALL THE TIME.
>> YOU JUMPED LIKE...
FIVE SHADES.
>> YEAH.
IT'S PRETTY MUCH JUST LIKE MY
REGULAR NIGHTLY ROUTINE.
IT WAS SO EASY.
>> IT WAS SIX MINUTES,
SIX SHADES, THAT'S ABOUT
A MINUTE PER SHADE.
>> WELL, I STARTED AT
THREE AND A HALF,
AND THEN I WENT DOWN
TO A ONE.
>> THERE WAS A HUGE DIFFERENCE.
FIVE TO ONE.
A ONE!
>> AFTER THE FIRST SIX MINUTES
OF USING SUPERSMILE
THE TINGE IN MY TEETH
WAS DRAMATIC.
AFTER A MONTH, MY TEETH
ARE EVEN WHITER,
AND THEY FEEL HEALTHY.
THEY FEEL GOOD.
THEY FEEL CLEAN.
>> AFTER USING SUPERSMILE
I DON'T THINK PEOPLE CAN TELL
THAT I USED TO SMOKE
OR THAT I DRINK COFFEE
ON A REGULAR BASIS.
>> I FEEL LIKE I DON'T HAVE
TO WORRY ABOUT A SPECIAL
OCCASION COMING UP.
AND, "OH, ARE MY TEETH
GOING TO LOOK WHITE?"
BECAUSE I'M CONSTANTLY
WITH THE PRODUCT,
THE SUPERSMILE PRODUCT,
MAINTAINING THAT NICE, BRIGHT,
WHITE SMILE EVERY DAY.
>> STOP BEING EMBARRASSED
BY YOUR SMILE BECAUSE NOW
YOU CAN TURN BACK THE CLOCK
ON YOUR TEETH AND SAFELY
GET A NATURALLY WHITER,
BRIGHTER, SEXIER SMILE.
NOW, YOU CAN WHITEN YOUR TEETH
SAFELY AND GENTLY EVERY DAY
BY MAKING THE SWITCH
TO SUPERSMILE.
THE ONLY WHITENING SYSTEM
WITH CALPROX.
>> YOU HAVE TIME TO BRUSH
YOUR TEETH REGULARLY, RIGHT?
WELL, THAT'S ALL IT TAKES.
>> THE SUPERSMILE SYSTEM
WORKS IN MINUTES TO SAFELY
REMOVE EMBARRASSING STAINS
FROM YOUR TEETH.
SUPERSMILE IS CLINICALLY SHOWN
TO WHITEN TEETH NEARLY
FIVE SHADES IN 30 DAYS
EVEN IF YOU CONTINUE TO SMOKE,
OR DRINK COFFEE, TEA,
OR RED WINE.
PLUS, SUPERSMILE ACTUALLY
STRENGTHENS YOUR ENAMEL
WITH CALCIUM, AND HELPS PREVENT
CAVITIES WITH FLUORIDE.
IT WORKS ON NATURAL TEETH,
AND WILL EVEN WHITEN VENEERS,
CAPS, BONDING, CROWNS,
AND DENTURES SO YOU CAN
SMILE WITH CONFIDENCE.
IN FACT, 100% OF CLINICAL STUDY
PARTICIPANTS SAW RESULTS
WITH SUPERSMILE.
>> THE BEAUTY OF IT IS THAT IT
CONTAINS A NUMBER OF MINERALS
AND PRODUCTS WITHIN IT THAT
REALLY PROMOTE TOOTH HEALTH
IN ADDITION TO ENHANCING
THE WHITENESS AND BRIGHTNESS
OF YOUR TOOTH.
>> HERE'S HOW SUPERSMILE WORKS.
START EACH DAY WITH
THE WHITENING PRE-RINSE.
THIS POWERFUL STAIN REDUCER
MAKES YOUR MOUTH MINTY FRESH.
AND IT SUPERCHARGES
THE RESULTS YOU'LL GET
FROM THE SUPERSMILE
PROFESSIONAL WHITENING
TOOTHPASTE AND ACCELERATOR.
THESE WORK TOGETHER TO REMOVE
STAINS IN THE TOOTH.
SURFACE STAINS FORM ON
A THIN LAYER ON YOUR TEETH.
MANY PRODUCTS SCRAPE THIS LAYER
AWAY WITH SILICA,
A TYPE OF SAND.
THIS CAN DAMAGE YOUR ENAMEL
AND TOOTH ENAMEL
DOESN'T GROW BACK.
SUPERSMILE IS SAFE AND GENTLE
BECAUSE IT'S THE ONLY
WHITENING SYSTEM
WITH THE PROPRIETARY
INGREDIENT, CALPROX.
JUST A DROP EACH OF
THE TOOTHPASTE WITH CALPROX,
AND THE WHITENING ACCELERATOR
ON YOUR DRYING SUPERSMILE
TOOTHBRUSH CREATE A DYNAMIC
WHITENING REACTION
THAT GENTLY LIFTS
AND DISSOLVES AWAY
SURFACE STAINS.
THERE'S NOTHING ELSE LIKE IT.
AND SUPERSMILE DOESN'T
STOP THERE.
IT ALSO QUICKLY AND SAFELY
LIFTS AWAY THOSE OLDER,
DEEPER, STUBBORN STAINS,
WITHIN THE TOOTH
LEAVING YOU WITH THE NATURALLY
WHITER, BRIGHTER, SEXIER SMILE
YOU'VE ALWAYS WANTED.
>> I COULD SEE, WITH MY
OWN EYES, THAT MY TEETH
WERE SO MUCH WHITER.
IT WAS INCREDIBLE.
>> YOUR SUPERSMILE SYSTEM
ALSO INCLUDES DR. SMIGEL'S
PATENTED TOOTHBRUSH.
ITS UNIQUE, INVERTED
V-SHAPED BRISTLES CLEAN
THE HARD TO REACH AREAS
BETWEEN YOUR TEETH AND GUMS.
AND LISTEN TO THIS,
YOUR SUPERSMILE SYSTEM
INCLUDES FIVE PROFESSIONAL
ACTIVATING RODS TO JUMP START
YOUR SUPERSMILE IN
JUST SIX MINUTES.
>> THEY REALLY MEAN IT.
IT IS SIX MINUTES.
HA-HA-HA!
>> I WAS LIKE EIGHT,
AND THAT'S PRETTY YELLOW.
NOW I'M THREE.
>> THIS EASY TO USE DESIGN
DISPENSES JUST THE RIGHT AMOUNT
OF AN INCREDIBLY EFFECTIVE
CLEANSING AGENT THAT IS
THE SAME AMAZING WHITENING
FORMULA DR. SMIGEL
USES IN HIS OFFICE.
USE ONCE A WEEK,
OR BEFORE A SPECIAL OCCASION,
AND THEN BRUSH NORMALLY
FOR A DAZZLING SMILE.
>> I JUST RUB IT ACROSS
MY TEETH, LEAVE IT ON,
THEN I COME OUT AND I BRUSH
AND, AMAZING.
SO WHITE.
>> MESSY TRAYS AND AWKWARD
STRIPS DON'T WHITEN ALL THE WAY
TO YOUR GUM LINE.
ABRASIVE PASTE CAN DAMAGE
YOUR ENAMEL.
PROFESSIONAL WHITENING
CAN CAUSE SENSITIVITY,
AND MAY COST $500 OR MORE
PER TREATMENT.
AND EVERY ONE OF THESE METHODS
WILL HAVE YOU STUCK IN
A RECURRING CYCLE OF
WHITENING AND FADING.
BUT NOW YOU CAN GET A WHITER,
BRIGHTER, HEALTHIER SMILE
SAFELY WITH SUPERSMILE
FOR ONLY $39.95.
AND IT GETS EVEN BETTER.
WHEN YOU CALL AND ORDER IN
THE NEXT 16 MINUTES YOU'LL GET
THREE FANTASTIC BONUS GIFTS
ABSOLUTELY FREE!
THE SUPERSMILE QUICKEE
INSTANT WHITENING POLISH
WITH CALPROX.
JUST SMOOTH A DROP OVER
YOUR TEETH WHEN YOU'RE
ON THE GO OR SIMPLY DON'T
HAVE TIME TO BRUSH YOUR TEETH.
THE SUPERSMILE PROFESSIONAL
WHITENING GUM WITH CALPROX
FRESHENS BREATH AND WHITENS
YOUR TEETH ONE SHADE
AFTER EATING OR DRINKING.
AND THE SUPERSMILE SHADE GUIDE.
TAKE YOUR OWN SUPERSMILE
CHALLENGE AND MEASURE EXACTLY
HOW MANY SHADES WHITER
YOUR SMILE BECOMES.
EVERYTHING YOU SEE HERE
IS VALUED AT OVER $90,
BUT BECAUSE DR. SMIGEL'S
TEAMING UP WITH GUTHY-RENKER
TO SELL DIRECTLY TO YOU
WITH NO RETAIL MARKUPS
WE ARE GIVING YOU
THE ULTIMATE INSIDER
PRICE REDUCTION.
SO YOU WON'T PAY $90
FOR SUPERSMILE,
YOU WON'T EVEN PAY $39.
ACT QUICKLY AND YOU'LL GET
SUPERSMILE FOR ONLY $29.95,
BUT WE'RE NOT DONE.
ORDER IN THE NEXT 15 MINUTES,
AND WE'LL INCLUDE SHIPPING
ABSOLUTELY FREE.
CALL NOW AND YOU'LL RECEIVE
A COMPLETE 30-DAY SUPPLY
OF SUPERSMILE AND ALL THESE
BONUS GIFTS AND FREE SHIPPING
ALL FOR THE AMAZING PRICE
OF $29.95.
>> IF YOU'RE NOT 100%
SATISFIED, SIMPLY RETURN
THE EMPTY TUBES WITHIN 60 DAYS
AND YOU'LL GET A COMPLETE
REFUND OF THE PURCHASE PRICE,
NO QUESTIONS ASKED.
>> IF YOU DECIDE TO RETURN
SUPERSMILE YOU CAN STILL
KEEP THE BONUS GIFTS
AS DR. SMIGEL'S WAY OF SAYING
THANK YOU FOR TRYING
SUPERSMILE.
THE SOONER YOU USE SUPERSMILE
THE FASTER YOU'LL SEE RESULTS.
BUT YOU ONLY HAVE
A LIMITED TIME
TO TRY THIS EXTRAORDINARY
TEETH WHITENING SYSTEM
AT THIS AMAZING LOW PRICE
OF ONLY $29.95.
AND RIGHT NOW SHIPPING
IS ABSOLUTELY FREE.
GET READY TO TURN YOUR SMILE
INTO A SUPERSMILE.
CALL RIGHT NOW.
>> I USE THE SUPERSMILE SYSTEM
EVERY SINGLE DAY AND I LOVE IT.
IT'S A TEETH WHITENING SYSTEM
UNLIKE ANY OTHER.
YOU'LL FIND SUPERSMILE
IN ALMOST EVERY
TOP BEAUTY MAGAZINE.
NOW, HEAR WHY MEN'S HEALTH
EDITOR, BRIAN BOYE SAYS
HIS READERS LOVE IT.
>> EVERY ONCE IN A WHILE
I DISCOVER A REALLY GREAT
PRODUCT THAT WORKS FOR ME,
AND I KNOW THAT IT'LL WORK
FOR OUR READERS.
I THINK THE MOST IMPORTANT
REASON THAT SUPERSMILE HAS WON
A MEN'S HEALTH GROOMING AWARD
THREE TIMES IS VERY SIMPLE,
AND THAT'S INNOVATION.
>> NEW BEAUTY PUBLISHER,
STEFFANIE ATTENBERG FEELS
CONFIDENT RECOMMENDING
SUPERSMILE TO HER READERS.
>> SUPERSMILE HAS WON
NUMEROUS AWARDS.
THEY'VE BEEN RECOGNIZED
FOR THE "BEST AT-HOME
WHITENING INNOVATION."
THEY'VE BEEN RECOGNIZED FOR
"BEST BREATH FRESHENER."
OUR READERS LOVE IT.
THE FEEDBACK HAS
BEEN PHENOMENAL.
>> RUBIN SINGER IS A TOP
NEW YORK FASHION DESIGNER
AND SHARES SUPERSMILE
EVERY CHANCE HE GETS.
>> WHEN I SHOW THE COLLECTION
DURING FASHION WEEK,
WE USUALLY PUT BAGS
AT THE FRONT ROW WHERE
ALL THE EDITORS, AND BUYERS,
AND CELEBRITIES SIT,
AND WE USE SUPERSMILE PRODUCTS
IN THE BAGS, AND WE'VE GOTTEN
THE MOST AMAZING FEEDBACK
FROM EVERYONE IN THE INDUSTRY.
SO, SUPERSMILE IS ALWAYS
A HUGE HIT.
♪
>> YOU KNOW EVERY DAY
I WAKE UP AND I WASH MY FACE.
I PUT MY MAKE-UP ON.
I SPEND A TON OF TIME
DECIDING WHAT TO WEAR.
USING SUPERSMILE THAT PACKAGE
IS COMPLETE.
>> I TRIED OTHER WHITENING
PRODUCTS AND I JUST FELT LIKE
I STILL HAD THE YELLOW FILM
YOU GET ON YOUR TEETH,
AND THEN SUPERSMILE,
WITHIN A MONTH,
I HAD LIKE THIS GREAT, CLEAN,
WHITE SMILE.
>> ACADEMY AWARD NOMINATED ACTOR
DANNY AIELLO IS A LONGTIME
PATIENT OF DR. SMIGEL,
AND ONE OF SUPERSMILE'S
BIGGEST FANS.
>> I DON'T USE ANYTHING ELSE,
BUT SUPERSMILE.
A SMILE MEANS SO MUCH.
A SMILE COMPLETELY RELEASES
YOUR ENTIRE BODY.
IF YOU CAN REALLY,
SMILE AND LET IT GO,
AND NOT WORRY,
AND SMILE...IT'S, IT'S,
IT'S A WONDERFUL FEELING.
>> IN CASE YOU'RE WONDERING,
NONE OF THE TESTIMONIALS
IN THIS SHOW OR THE DENTISTS
YOU'VE SEEN HAVE BEEN PAID
TO SHARE THEIR OPINIONS.
THEY'RE APPEARING BECAUSE
THEY BELIEVE SO STRONGLY
IN DR. SMIGEL AND HIS AMAZING
SUPERSMILE SYSTEM.
>> SUPERSMILE IS IN
A LEAGUE OF ITS OWN.
THERE IS NOT ANOTHER PRODUCT
THAT I AM AWARE OF
THAT CAN EVEN BEGIN TO COMPARE.
>> HE'S GIVING THE PATIENT
EVERYTHING THAT WE KNOW
THAT THE PATIENT NEEDS.
>> I USE IT MYSELF, EVERY DAY.
>> IT'S UNIQUE.
IT'S DIFFERENT THAN ANY
OTHER SYSTEM ON THE MARKET.
>> THE CALPROX GENTLY REMOVES
THE PELLICLE ON THE TOOTH
WHICH IS AN OUTSIDE SURFACE
LAYER ON THE TOOTH.
THAT ALLOWS THE ACTIVE
INGREDIENT TO GET INTO
THE ENAMEL AND ALLOW
THE LIGHTENING EFFECT
TO BE ENHANCED.
IT WORKS SO WELL
THAT I EVEN USE IT
IN MY PRACTICE WHEN
I CLEAN PEOPLE'S TEETH.
SUPERSMILE REALLY
WORKS THE BEST.
IT JUST WORKS THE BEST, PERIOD.
>> I GET THE BEST CHECKUPS
SINCE I'VE STARTED
USING SUPERSMILE.
I'M IN AND OUT.
I HAVE NO CAVITIES.
I HAVE NO PROBLEMS.
I HAVE NO ISSUES.
>> COMING UP,
MEET THE BRILLIANT MAN
BEHIND THE BREAKTHROUGH
SUPERSMILE PROFESSIONAL
WHITENING SYSTEM,
THE ONE AND ONLY
DR. IRWIN SMIGEL.
>> I'VE WATCHED DENTISTS
AROUND HIM,
GATHER AROUND HIM,
HE'S LIKE A KING.
>> NOW, YOU CAN TURN BACK
THE CLOCK ON YOUR TEETH
AND SAFELY GET A NATURALLY
WHITER, BRIGHTER, SEXIER SMILE
WITH SUPERSMILE.
SUPERSMILE IS CLINICALLY
SHOWN TO WHITEN TEETH
NEARLY FIVE SHADES IN 30 DAYS
EVEN IF YOU CONTINUE TO SMOKE,
OR DRINK COFFEE, TEA,
OR RED WINE.
HERE'S HOW IT WORKS.
START EACH DAY WITH
A WHITENING PRE-RINSE.
THIS POWERFUL STAIN REDUCER
MAKES YOUR MOUTH MINTY FRESH.
AND IT SUPERCHARGES THE RESULTS
YOU'LL GET FROM THE SUPERSMILE
PROFESSIONAL WHITENING
TOOTHPASTE AND ACCELERATOR.
THESE WORK TOGETHER TO REMOVE
STAINS IN THE TOOTH.
SUPERSMILE IS SAFE AND GENTLE
BECAUSE IT'S THE ONLY
WHITENING SYSTEM
WITH THE PROPRIETARY
INGREDIENT, CALPROX.
YOUR SUPERSMILE SYSTEM
ALSO INCLUDES DR. SMIGEL'S
PATENTED TOOTHBRUSH.
ITS UNIQUE, INVERTED
V-SHAPED BRISTLES CLEAN
THE HARD TO REACH AREAS BETWEEN
YOUR TEETH AND GUMS.
AND THE SHAPE OF THE HANDLE
GUIDES YOU TO BRUSH CORRECTLY
AT THE ADA RECOMMENDED
45 DEGREE ANGLE.
AND LISTEN TO THIS,
YOUR SUPERSMILE SYSTEM
INCLUDES FIVE
PROFESSIONAL ACTIVATING RODS
TO JUMP START YOUR SUPERSMILE
IN JUST SIX MINUTES.
THIS EASY TO USE DESIGN
DISPENSES JUST THE RIGHT AMOUNT
OF AN INCREDIBLY EFFECTIVE
CLEANSING AGENT THAT IS
THE SAME AMAZING WHITENING
FORMULA DR. SMIGEL
USES IN HIS OFFICE.
NOW, YOU CAN GET A WHITER,
BRIGHTER, HEALTHIER SMILE
SAFELY WITH SUPERSMILE
FOR ONLY $39.95.
AND IT GETS EVEN BETTER.
WHEN YOU CALL AND ORDER
IN THE NEXT SEVEN MINUTES
YOU'LL GET THREE FANTASTIC
BONUS GIFTS ABSOLUTELY FREE!
SUPERSMILE'S QUICK INSTANT
WHITENING POLISH WITH CALPROX,
THE SUPERSMILE PROFESSIONAL
WHITENING GUM WITH CALPROX,
AND THE SUPERSMILE SHADE GUIDE.
EVERYTHING YOU SEE HERE
IS VALUED AT OVER $90,
BUT BECAUSE DR. SMIGEL
IS TEAMING UP WITH GUTHY-RENKER
TO SELL DIRECTLY TO YOU
WITH NO RETAIL MARKUPS
WE ARE GIVING YOU THE ULTIMATE
INSIDER PRICE REDUCTION.
ORDER IN THE NEXT SIX MINUTES
AND YOU'LL RECEIVE A COMPLETE
30-DAY SUPPLY OF SUPERSMILE
AND ALL THESE BONUS GIFTS
FOR THE AMAZING PRICE
OF $29.95.
AND RIGHT NOW, SHIPPING IS
ABSOLUTELY FREE.
>> IF YOU'RE NOT 100%
SATISFIED, SIMPLY RETURN
THE EMPTY TUBES WITHIN 60 DAYS
AND YOU'LL GET A COMPLETE
REFUND OF THE PURCHASE PRICE,
NO QUESTIONS ASKED.
>> IF YOU DECIDE TO RETURN
SUPERSMILE YOU CAN STILL KEEP
THE BONUS GIFTS AS DR. SMIGEL'S
WAY OF SAYING THANK YOU.
YOU ONLY HAVE A LIMITED TIME
TO TRY THIS EXTRAORDINARY
TEETH WHITENING SYSTEM
AT THIS AMAZING LOW PRICE
OF ONLY $29.95.
AND FOR A LIMITED TIME,
SHIPPING IS ABSOLUTELY FREE.
GET READY TO TURN YOUR SMILE
INTO A SUPERSMILE.
CALL RIGHT NOW.
>> DR. IRWIN SMIGEL IS
RECOGNIZED BY
NEW YORK UNIVERSITY
AS THE FATHER OF
AESTHETIC DENTISTRY.
THAT'S THE ART AND SCIENCE
OF MAKING YOUR TEETH,
AND YOUR SMILE, HEALTHIER
AND MORE BEAUTIFUL.
HE'S WORLD-RENOWNED FOR BEING
THE ORIGINAL CREATOR
OF TOOTH BONDING.
AND HE IS THE ONLY DENTIST
WITH A PERMANENT EXHIBIT
IN THE SMITHSONIAN'S
NATIONAL MUSEUM OF DENTISTRY.
>> DR. SMIGEL IS A LIVING
LEGEND OF COSMETIC DENTISTRY.
>> HE'S THE GUY WHO MADE IT COOL
TO BE AN AESTHETIC DENTIST.
>> IRWIN'S IMPACT IN
THE DENTAL PROFESSION IS HUGE.
>> WHEN HE STANDS BEHIND
SOMETHING WE KNOW THAT IT WORKS.
>> DR. SMIGEL, WHY DO YOU
THINK SO MANY PEOPLE ARE
INTERESTED THESE DAYS
IN WHITENING THEIR TEETH?
>> EVERYONE WANTS TO LOOK
AS ATTRACTIVE AS POSSIBLE.
THROUGH THE AGES PEOPLE HAVE
BEEN TRYING TO WHITEN
THEIR TEETH.
UNFORTUNATELY, MOST OF THEM
DID MORE DAMAGE THAN GOOD.
>> BECAUSE TRADITIONALLY
WITH BLEACHING YOU HAVE TO
STOP AT SOME POINT.
>> YOU CAN'T BLEACH
YOUR TEETH INDEFINITELY.
EVENTUALLY IT'LL IRRITATE
THE GUM TISSUES OR EVEN
DAMAGE THE ENAMEL.
I'VE SEEN THE RESULTS
OF BAD BLEACHING.
OF PEOPLE WHO DAMAGE THEIR GUMS.
I MADE UP MY MIND THAT I WOULD
DEVELOP SOMETHING THAT,
NO MATTER WHAT, WOULD NOT
DO ANY DAMAGE TO THE TEETH.
>> WE HEARD A LOT ABOUT
OTHER WHITENING PRODUCTS.
YOURS IS DIFFERENT,
AND IT'S THAT GREAT PROPRIETARY
INGREDIENT CALPROX, ISN'T IT?
>> THE PROBLEM WITH
WHITENING TOOTHPASTE IS THAT
THEY HAVE TO GET RID OF
THE CAUSE OF THE STAIN
WHICH IS A BIOFILM
THAT FORMS ON THE TEETH.
ALL THE WHITENING TOOTHPASTES
USE SILICA, AN ABRASIVE,
TO GET RID OF IT.
NOW, WHEN YOU USE AN ABRASIVE
IT CAN WEAR AWAY THE ENAMEL.
AND ENAMEL DOES NOT GROW BACK.
>> GOOD POINT.
>> AND WHAT THE BEAUTY
OF CALPROX IS
IT ACTUALLY REDUCES THIS
WITHOUT BEING ABRASIVE.
IT'S HEALTHY FOR THE GUMS
AND THE TEETH.
THERE'S NEVER BEEN
A TOOTHPASTE LIKE THIS.
>> EVERY TIME I USE SUPERSMILE
I FEEL LIKE I JUST LEFT
THE DENTIST'S OFFICE.
I DON'T FEEL LIKE I NEED
ANYTHING ELSE IN ORDER
TO HAVE A GREAT SMILE.
>> I'VE BEEN USING SUPERSMILE
FOR FOUR YEARS.
A FEW MONTHS AFTER I HAD STARTED
USING IT I WENT TO THE DENTIST
AND HE WAS LIKE,
"YOU HAVE TO TELL ME
WHAT YOU'RE USING.
YOUR TEETH HAVE NEVER BEEN
IN SUCH GOOD SHAPE."
AND I WAS LIKE,
"REALLY?
SUPERSMILE."
>> IN THIS SHOW YOU'VE SEEN
WHAT A DIFFERENCE SUPERSMILE
CAN MAKE FOR PEOPLE
JUST LIKE YOU.
YOU'VE SEEN PEOPLE TRY
THE SUPERSMILE SYSTEM
FOR THE VERY FIRST TIME.
THE SAME SYSTEM YOU CAN GET
AT HOME AND YOU'VE HEARD
THEIR HONEST REACTIONS RIGHT
AFTER THEY SAW THE AMAZING
RESULTS WITH THEIR OWN EYES.
>> IT FEELS LIKE I'VE JUST
GONE TO THE DENTIST
AND HAD THEM
PROFESSIONALLY CLEANED.
>> SMOOTH, CLEAN, SPARKLY,
HEALTHY, HA-HA.
>> IF THAT CAN HAPPEN
IN SIX MINUTES, WHAT CAN
HAPPEN IN A WEEK?
OR A MONTH?
>> YOU'VE HEARD FROM PEOPLE
WHO'VE SHARED THEIR AMAZING
RESULTS AFTER USING SUPERSMILE
FOR 30 DAYS.
>> IT'S AMAZING TO ME
HOW MY SMILE JUST KEEPS
GETTING WHITER AND BRIGHTER.
>> I DON'T HAVE TO WORRY ABOUT
STAINS ACCUMULATING ON MY TEETH.
I KNOW THAT I'M GOING TO BE
USING THE PRODUCTS AGAIN,
AND RE-WHITENING MY TEETH
EVERY SINGLE DAY.
>> PEOPLE WHO HAVE BEEN USING
SUPERSMILE FOR YEARS
SWEAR BY IT TO KEEP THEIR
SMILES WHITE, AND THEIR
TEETH AND GUMS HEALTHIER.
>> I'VE BEEN USING SUPERSMILE
FOR THE PAST THREE YEARS.
MY HYGIENIST AND THE DENTIST
BOTH SAID THAT MY TEETH
ARE PRETTY BORING NOW.
WHICH IS NOT BAD.
>> I LIKE THE SIMPLICITY
OF SUPERSMILE.
I LIKE THE PRODUCT LINE.
I LIKE THE RESULTS.
>> I STARTED USING SUPERSMILE
ABOUT SIX YEARS AGO.
AS SOON AS I STARTED
USING IT PEOPLE WOULD BE LIKE,
"WOW, LINDSAY, YOUR TEETH
ARE BEAUTIFUL."
>> MAGAZINE EDITORS,
CELEBRITIES, FASHION DESIGNERS,
AND TOP DENTISTS HAVE ALL
VOLUNTEERED TO APPEAR
IN THIS SHOW BECAUSE THEY'VE
SEEN THEIR OWN AMAZING RESULTS
WITH SUPERSMILE.
>> IT'S AN EASY PRODUCT
TO USE AND IT DELIVERS
THAT GREAT SMILE THAT
GUYS ARE LOOKING FOR.
>> YOU DON'T HAVE TO WORRY
THAT IT'S CAUSING ANY DAMAGE
TO YOUR ENAMEL WHILE GETTING
THAT WHITE, BEAUTIFUL SMILE.
>> I'M GONNA KEEP USING
SUPERSMILE BECAUSE I WANT
MY TEETH TO BE WHITE.
AND I WANT THEM TO BE HEALTHY.
>> STOP BEING EMBARRASSED
BY YOUR SMILE.
BECAUSE NOW YOU CAN WHITEN
YOU TEETH SAFELY
AND GENTLY EVERY DAY
BY MAKING THE SWITCH
TO SUPERSMILE.
THE ONLY WHITENING SYSTEM
WITH CALPROX.
>> I JUST BRUSH MY TEETH
AND WATCH THEM GET WHITER.
>> THE SUPERSMILE SYSTEM
WORKS IN MINUTES TO SAFELY
REMOVE EMBARRASSING STAINS
FROM YOUR TEETH.
SUPERSMILE IS CLINICALLY
SHOWN TO WHITEN TEETH
NEARLY FIVE SHADES IN 30 DAYS
EVEN IF YOU CONTINUE TO SMOKE,
OR DRINK COFFEE, TEA,
OR RED WINE.
PLUS, SUPERSMILE ACTUALLY
STRENGTHENS YOUR ENAMEL
WITH CALCIUM AND HELPS
PREVENT CAVITIES WITH FLUORIDE.
IT WORKS ON NATURAL TEETH
AND WILL EVEN WHITEN
VENEERS, CAPS, BONDING,
CROWNS, AND DENTURES
SO YOU CAN SMILE
WITH CONFIDENCE.
IN FACT, 100% OF CLINICAL
STUDY PARTICIPANTS SAW RESULTS
WITH SUPERSMILE.
>> YOU'RE GOING TO GET
A NICE, WHITER SMILE,
BUT IN ADDITION TO THAT
YOU'RE GOING TO PROMOTE
ORAL HEALTH.
HEALTHIER GUMS, HEALTHIER TEETH.
>> THE SUPERSMILE SYSTEM
IS SIMPLE AND SAFE,
AND GENTLE ENOUGH TO USE
EVERY DAY.
HERE'S HOW IT WORKS.
START EACH DAY WITH
THE WHITENING PRE-RINSE.
THIS POWERFUL STAIN REDUCER
MAKES YOUR MOUTH MINTY FRESH,
AND IT SUPERCHARGES THE RESULTS
YOU'LL GET FROM
THE SUPERSMILE PROFESSIONAL
WHITENING TOOTHPASTE,
AND ACCELERATOR.
THESE WORK TOGETHER
TO REMOVE STAINS IN THE TOOTH.
SURFACE STAINS FORM ON
A THIN LAYER ON YOUR TEETH.
MANY PRODUCTS SCRAPE THIS LAYER
AWAY WITH SILICA,
A TYPE OF SAND.
THIS CAN DAMAGE YOUR ENAMEL
AND TOOTH ENAMEL
DOESN'T GROW BACK.
SUPERSMILE IS SAFE AND GENTLE
BECAUSE IT'S THE ONLY
WHITENING SYSTEM
WITH THE PROPRIETARY
INGREDIENT, CALPROX.
JUST A DROP EACH OF
THE TOOTHPASTE WITH CALPROX
AND THE WHITENING ACCELERATOR
ON YOUR DRYING SUPERSMILE
TOOTHBRUSH CREATE A DYNAMIC
WHITENING REACTION THAT
GENTLY LIFTS AND DISSOLVES
AWAY SURFACE STAINS.
THERE'S NOTHING ELSE LIKE IT.
AND SUPERSMILE DOESN'T
STOP THERE.
IT ALSO QUICKLY AND SAFELY
LIFTS AWAY THOSE OLDER, DEEPER,
STUBBORN STAINS WITHIN
THE TOOTH LEAVING YOU WITH
THE NATURALLY WHITER,
BRIGHTER, SEXIER SMILE
YOU'VE ALWAYS WANTED.
>> IT'S AMAZING TO ME
HOW MY SMILE JUST KEEPS
GETTING WHITER AND BRIGHTER.
>> YOUR SUPERSMILE SYSTEM
ALSO INCLUDES DR. SMIGEL'S
PATENTED TOOTHBRUSH.
ITS UNIQUE INVERTED V-SHAPED
BRISTLES CLEAN THE HARD
TO REACH AREAS BETWEEN
YOUR TEETH AND GUMS.
AND LISTEN TO THIS,
YOUR SUPERSMILE SYSTEM
INCLUDES FIVE
PROFESSIONAL ACTIVATING RODS
TO JUMP START YOUR SUPERSMILE
IN JUST SIX MINUTES.
THIS EASY TO USE DESIGN
DISPENSES JUST THE RIGHT AMOUNT
OF AN INCREDIBLY EFFECTIVE
CLEANSING AGENT THAT IS
THE SAME AMAZING WHITENING
FORMULA DR. SMIGEL
USES IN HIS OFFICE.
USE ONCE A WEEK OR
BEFORE A SPECIAL OCCASION
AND THEN BRUSH NORMALLY
FOR A DAZZLING SMILE.
>> I JUST RUB IT ACROSS
MY TEETH, LEAVE IT ON,
THEN I COME OUT AND I BRUSH,
AND AMAZING.
SO WHITE.
>> MESSY TRAYS AND AWKWARD
STRIPS DON'T WHITEN ALL THE WAY
TO YOUR GUM LINE.
ABRASIVE PASTE CAN
DAMAGE YOUR ENAMEL.
PROFESSIONAL WHITENING CAN
CAUSE SENSITIVITY AND MAY
COST $500 OR MORE PER TREATMENT
AND EVERY ONE OF THESE METHODS
WILL HAVE YOU STUCK IN
A RECURRING CYCLE OF
WHITENING AND FADING.
BUT NOW, YOU CAN GET A WHITER,
BRIGHTER, HEALTHIER SMILE
SAFELY WITH SUPERSMILE
FOR ONLY $39.95.
SWITCH TO SUPERSMILE
TO GENTLY WHITEN YOUR TEETH
AND KEEP THEM WHITE
EVERY TIME YOU BRUSH.
AND IT GETS EVEN BETTER.
WHEN YOU CALL AND ORDER
IN THE NEXT THREE MINUTES
YOU'LL GET THREE FANTASTIC
BONUS GIFTS ABSOLUTELY FREE!
THE SUPERSMILE QUICKEE
INSTANT WHITENING POLISH
WITH CALPROX.
JUST SMOOTH A DROP OVER
YOUR TEETH WHEN YOU'RE
ON THE GO OR SIMPLY DON'T
HAVE TIME TO BRUSH YOUR TEETH.
THE SUPERSMILE PROFESSIONAL
WHITENING GUM WITH CALPROX
FRESHENS BREATH AND WHITENS
YOUR TEETH ONE SHADE
AFTER EATING OR DRINKING.
AND THE SUPERSMILE
SHADE GUIDE.
TAKE YOUR OWN SUPERSMILE
CHALLENGE AND MEASURE
EXACTLY HOW MANY SHADES WHITER
YOUR SMILE BECOMES.
>> JUST GAVE MY TEETH
KIND OF A GLOW THAT
I HAVEN'T SEEN BEFORE.
>> I HAVE LIKE SO MUCH
MORE CONFIDENCE TO SMILE.
>> EVERYTHING YOU SEE HERE
IS VALUED AT OVER $90,
BUT BECAUSE DR. SMIGEL IS
TEAMING UP WITH GUTHY-RENKER
TO SELL DIRECTLY TO YOU
WITH NO RETAIL MARKUPS
WE ARE GIVING YOU THE ULTIMATE
INSIDER PRICE REDUCTION.
SO YOU WON'T PAY $90
FOR SUPERSMILE.
YOU WON'T EVEN PAY $39.
ACT QUICKLY AND YOU'LL GET
SUPERSMILE FOR ONLY $29.95,
BUT WE'RE NOT DONE.
ORDER IN THE NEXT TWO MINUTES
AND WE'LL INCLUDE SHIPPING
ABSOLUTELY FREE.
CALL NOW AND YOU'LL RECEIVE
A COMPLETE 30-DAY SUPPLY
OF SUPERSMILE, AND ALL THESE
BONUS GIFTS,
AND FREE SHIPPING,
ALL FOR THE AMAZING PRICE
OF $29.95.
>> IF YOU'RE NOT 100% SATISFIED
SIMPLY RETURN THE EMPTY TUBES
WITHIN 60 DAYS AND YOU'LL GET
A COMPLETE REFUND OF
THE PURCHASE PRICE,
NO QUESTIONS ASKED.
>> IF YOU DECIDE TO RETURN
SUPERSMILE YOU CAN STILL
KEEP THE BONUS GIFTS
AS DR. SMIGEL'S WAY OF SAYING
THANK YOU FOR TRYING
SUPERSMILE.
THE SOONER YOU USE SUPERSMILE,
THE FASTER YOU'LL SEE RESULTS,
BUT YOU ONLY HAVE
A LIMITED TIME
TO TRY THIS EXTRAOINARY
TEETH WHITENING SYSTEM
AT THIS AMAZING LOW PRICE
OF ONLY $29.95.
AND RIGHT NOW SHIPPING
IS ABSOLUTELY FREE.
GET READY TO TURN YOUR SMILE
INTO A SUPERSMILE.
CALL RIGHT NOW.
>> THE PRECEDING HAS BEEN
A PAID PRESENTATION
FOR SUPERSMILE BROUGHT TO YOU
BY GUTHY-RENKER.
(John H.) OH, THE WEATHER
OUTSIDE IS FRIGHTFUL,
BUT THE WIPEOUTS
ARE SO DELIGHTFUL.
I AM LORD OF THE BALLS!
(roars)
(John A.) THAT'S RIGHT.
BUNDLE UP, AMERICA.
(man) OH, MY GOD!
WINTER "WIPEOUT" IS BACK...
(woman) AAH!
WITH AN ALL-NEW OBSTACLE COURSE
THAT WILL SNOWBLOW YOU AWAY.
I'M SO EXCITED AND SCARED
AT THE SAME TIME!
24 WINDCHILLED WARRIORS
ARE ABOUT TO GO HEAD-TO-HEAD
IN A FRIGID FREE-FOR-ALL
FOR $50,000.
OH, MY GOD. NO WAY.
YOU GOTTA BE KIDDING ME!
WE'LL HAVE
AN AVALANCHE OF FALLS...
OH!
SHIVERING SPILLS...
UHH!
AND BITTER-COLD BLUNDERS.
ONLY THREE WILL ADVANCE TO FACE
THE FREEZING TEMPERATURES
OF OUR MOST CHALLENGING
OBSTACLE COURSE OF ALL--