BUT WILLIAMS IS
NOT CHOOSING JUNK FOOD,
SHE WANTS TO FEED HER FAMILY
HEALTHY MEALS, THAT'S WHY
SHE HAS CANNED AND FROZEN
VEGETABLES IN HER CART.
A MOVE THAT DIETICIAN
PENNY WILSON SAYS IS SMART.
YOU CAN SAVE MONEY AND EAT
WELL AT THE SAME TIME.
TIP NUMBER ONE.
TO SAVE ON FOOD, CHOOSE
FROZEN OVER FRESH, ITS
USUALLY CHEAPER.
BECAUSE THE FROZEN VEGETABLES
ARE PICKED AT THE PEAK OF
RIPENESS AND FROZEN RIGHT THEN.
TAKE FOR EXAMPLE BROCCOLI,
WE FOUND IT FOR 2.18 FRESH,
BUT IN THE FROZEN FOOD SECTION
BROCCOLI CUTS COST $1 A BAG
FOR ABOUT THE SAME SIZE
AS THE FRESH BUNCH.
AND YOU DON'T HAVE
TO WORRY ABOUT
THEM GOING BAD.
TIP NUMBER TWO GO
FOR CANNED VEGGIES.
WE GREW UP ON CANNED
VEGETABLES, THAT'S ALL
WE HAD IN MY HOUSE.
WILSON SAYS WHILE FRESH
PRODUCE IS ALWAYS A GREAT OPTION
SHE SAYS CANNED VEGETABLES
ARE A GOOD SUBSTITUTE.
JUST READ THE LABELS.
STILL 10% ONE THING YOU WANT TO
LOOK FOR IS IF YOU CAN GET
THE ONES WITH NO ADDED SALT.
BECAUSE THEY DO TEND
TO ADD SALT INTO
CANNED VEGETABLES.
TIP NUMBER THREE BEANS
ARE A SUPER FOOD.
A LOT OF PEOPLE DON'T
REALIZE BEANS ARE A GOOD
SOURCE OF PROTEIN AND FIBER.
SHE SAYS CANNED BEANS ARE
A GREAT OPTION BUT TO SAVE EVEN
MORE PICK UP SOME DRIED BEANS.
YEAH, YOU'RE GOING TO GET
MORE OVERALL WITH THAT.
TIP NUMBER FOUR BUY YOUR
GRAINS FROM THE BULK FOOD
CONTAINERS LIKE OATS OR
BROWN RICE, WILSON SAYS
YOU WILL SAVE A BUNDLE,
FOR EXAMPLE WE PICKED UP
A POUND OF STEEL CUT OATS OF
1.29 VS 4.69 FOR A POUND AND
A HALF WE FOUND ON THE SHELF.
FINALLY PICK SUPER FOODS
THAT ARE JAMMED PACKED WITH
VITAMINS AND BUDGET-FRIENDLY
THESE INCLUDE SWEET POTATOES,
APPLES AND KALE.
FOR TIPS ON THESE GO TO
OUR WEBSITE
LIVEWELLNETWORK.COM AND
CLICK ON DEALS.
THAT WILL DO IT FOR
THIS ADDITION OF DEALS.
WHAT'S YOUR DEAL?
WE ALWAYS WANT TO HEAR
YOUR MONEY SAVING IDEAS
AND TALK TO US ANYTIME ONLINE.
UNTIL NEXT TIME
I'M KAT COSLEY
THANKS SO MUCH FOR JOINING US.
ñúA
[CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
DISNEY-ABC DOMESTIC TELEVISION]
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
Meredith: THANK YOU.
GOOD LUCK.
HELLO, EVERYBODY, AND WELCOME
TO "MILLIONAIRE." ALL GREAT
CHAMPIONS KNOW THAT IT TAKES
PREPARATION AND HOURS OF
TRAINING TO BECOME THE BEST.
TODAY'S FIRST CONTESTANT HAS
BEEN TRAINING FOR "MILLIONAIRE"
NONSTOP AND HOPES TO BE THE
BEST WE'VE EVER HAD. FROM
ELKINS PARK, PENNSYLVANIA,
PLEASE WELCOME RYAN CARLIN.
HEY, RYAN, HOW ARE YOU?
>> NICE TO MEET YOU.
Meredith: NICE TO MEET YOU.
ALL RIGHT, RYAN, HOW HAVE YOU
BEEN TRAINING FOR TODAY?
>> HOW HAVE I NOT BEEN TRAINING
FOR TODAY? TRIVIA BOOKS, I'VE
WATCHED, I THINK, 27 OF THE
LAST 30 BEST PICTURES...
Meredith: REALLY?
>> REALLY.
Meredith: WHAT ELSE?
>> UM, THERE'S A BOOK, "8,888
TRIVIA QUESTIONS IN 365 DAYS."
I DID ABOUT 7,000 OF THOSE IN 4
DAYS, SO--
Meredith: WOW.
>> YEAH. I THINK I FORGOT THIRD
GRADE, BUT EVERYTHING ELSE
IS--IT'S TOTALLY IN THERE.
Meredith: IT'S ALL JAMMED IN
THERE, YOU THINK? EASILY
RETRIEVABLE?
>> EASILY RETRIEVABLE. IF I DID
A SHOT OF TEQUILA, I WOULD LOSE
A LOT OF IT, SO...
Meredith: ALL RIGHT, RYAN.
>> I'M HOLDING ON.
Meredith: I HOPE NOT, TOO.
LET'S SEE THE MONEY IN YOUR
ROUND ONE. COMPUTER, PLEASE
RANDOMIZE THE MONEY. AND NOW
LET'S SEE THE CATEGORIES TO
YOUR QUESTIONS. AND, COMPUTER,
PLEASE RANDOMIZE THE QUESTIONS.
AND NOW THAT EVERYTHING IS
SHUFFLED, ARE YOU READY?
>> I AM READY.
Meredith: AUDIENCE, ARE YOU
READY?
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
THEN LET'S PLAY "MILLIONAIRE."
ALL RIGHT, RYAN, HERE'S YOUR
FIRST QUESTION. A 12th-CENTURY
FRENCH KING WHO LACKED THE
ABILITY TO MOUNT A HORSE ON HIS
OWN, LOUIS VI WAS KNOWN BY WHAT
NICKNAME?
LOUIS THE WISE, LOUIS THE
HAIRY, LOUIS THE FAT, LOUIS THE
MESSY.
>> WELL, BEING SMART, HAIRY, OR
SLOPPY IS NOT GONNA PREVENT YOU
FROM GETTING ON A HORSE, BUT
I'M GONNA SAY "C," LOUIS THE
FAT, FINAL ANSWER.
Meredith: LOUIS THE FAT IS
ABSOLUTELY RIGHT. LET'S START
BUILDING YOUR BANK. HOW MUCH
MONEY BEHIND THIS QUESTION?
$3,000. GOOD START. YOU ARE 13
AWAY FROM A MILLION DOLLARS.
"ONLINE SEARCH" IS THE NEXT
CATEGORY. A VERMONT COMPANY
THAT SELLS WHAT EQUIPMENT HAS A
NATIONWIDE DATABASE ON ITS
WEBSITE FOR USERS TO FIND A
HILL?
ICE SKATES, TRAMPOLINES, SLEDS,
KITES.
>> ICE SKATES ARE FINDING A
POND, FINDING WIND, FINDING
JUMP--IT'S GOT TO BE SLEDS.
VERMONT, SLEDS. "C," SLEDS,
FINAL ANSWER.
Meredith: YES, IT IS SLEDS. YOU
NEED A HILL IF YOU'VE GOT A
SLED. ALL RIGHT, YOU HAVE 3,000
SO FAR. TO THAT WE'RE GONNA ADD
ANOTHER WHAT? LET'S SEE WHAT'S
BEHIND THIS QUESTION. ANOTHER
2,000. 5,000 IN YOUR BANK, 12
AWAY FROM A MILLION. "INDIRECT
INVENTIONS" IS THE CATEGORY.
HERE'S THE QUESTION. BECAUSE HE
ADVOCATED USING SPIRITUALITY TO
HEAL ALCOHOLISM, WHAT FAMOUS
THINKER IS CREDITED WITH
INDIRECTLY DEVELOPING
ALCOHOLICS ANONYMOUS?
CARL JUNG, L. RON HUBBARD,
MAHATMA GANDHI, ALFRED ADLER.
>> HMM.
Meredith: COME UPON THIS IN
YOUR TRIVIA?
>> WELL, I KNOW 3 OF THE NAMES
PRETTY WELL. OOH. ALTHOUGH
SPIRITUALITY...
ONE OF THOSE LEAPS OUT AS BEING
PRETTY SPIRITUAL, BUT ONE OF
THEM FOUNDED A RELIGION. ONE OF
THEM WAS A PSYCHOLOGIST. I'M
NOT SURE WHO THE OTHER ONE IS.
Meredith: WELL, YOU DO HAVE
LIFELINES IF YOU NEED THEM.
>> YEAH, AND I THINK BECAUSE
I'M TORN BETWEEN TWO THAT I
CAN'T LEAN TOWARDS ONE OR THE
OTHER. I'M GONNA HAVE TO JUMP
THIS QUESTION.
Meredith: WHAT ARE YOU TORN
BETWEEN?
>> I'M TORN BETWEEN, AH, ADLER
AND GANDHI.
Meredith: OK, LET'S SEE WHAT
THE RIGHT ANSWER IS. CARL JUNG.
I'M GLAD YOU JUMPED IT. ALL
RIGHT, RYAN, LET'S SEE HOW MUCH
YOU JUMPED OVER. QUESTION WAS
WORTH $5,000. OK, YOU FORFEIT
THE 5,000, BUT BY JUMPING THE
QUESTION, WHICH YOU DIDN'T
KNOW...
>> I'M STILL ALIVE.
Meredith: YOU'RE STILL ALIVE.
THAT'S RIGHT, 11 AWAY FROM A
MILLION. "THE SOUNDS OF MUSIC"
IS THE CATEGORY.
A PAINTING ON DISPLAY AT THE
COUNTRY MUSIC HALL OF FAME,
"THE SOURCES OF COUNTRY MUSIC,"
SHOWS MUSICIANS ONLY PLAYING
WHAT?
BRASS INSTRUMENTS, PERCUSSION
INSTRUMENTS, STRING
INSTRUMENTS, WOODWIND
INSTRUMENTS.
"THE SOURCES OF COUNTRY MUSIC."
>> I DON'T THINK IT'S WOODWIND,
BECAUSE I CAN'T THINK OF TOO
MANY FLUTE COUNTRY SONGS. I
HEAR A LOT OF COUNTRY SONGS,
THOUGH, THAT PLAY THE GUITAR. I
THINK EVERY COUNTRY SONG PLAYS
THE GUITAR.
NOT PERCUSSION. BRASS WOULD BE
MORE JAZZ TO ME.
[SIGH]
I'M GONNA GO WITH "C," STRING
INSTRUMENTS.
Meredith: FINAL ANSWER?
>> THOSE ARE TOUGH WORDS. "C,"
STRING INSTRUMENTS, FINAL
ANSWER.
Meredith: YES, IT IS STRING
INSTRUMENTS. GUITARS AND BANJOS
AND...LET'S SEE HOW MUCH MONEY
IS BEHIND THIS QUESTION.
$25,000. NICELY DONE, RYAN
CARLIN. A FIST PUMP TO HIS DAD
OVER THERE. WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK
WITH MORE "MILLIONAIRE."
Whatever it takes,
get to Sears Super Saturday,
with Friday preview.
Coats are 19.99,
and save even more with pass.
Get ½ Carat Diamond
earrings for $49.99.
Plus, all Craftsman wrench
sets are on sale.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
PREGO?!
BUT I'VE BOUGHT RAGU FOR YEARS.
[ Thinking ] WONDER WHAT OTHER
QUESTIONABLE CHOICES I'VE MADE?
I CHOOSE DATE NUMBER 2!
WHOOO!
[ sigh of relief ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHOOSE TASTE. CHOOSE PREGO.
Meredith: WE ARE BACK WITH RYAN
CARLIN FROM ELKINS PARK,
PENNSYLVANIA. RIGHT BEFORE THEGA
LITTLE BIT WITH YOUR DAD, DAN,
WHO'S OVER THERE. NICE TO SEE
YOU, DAN, AS WELL. WELCOME TO
THE SHOW.
[APPLAUSE]
NOW, SO FAR, HAS ALL THOSE
HOURS OF TRIVIA PLAYED INTO ANY
OF THESE ANSWERS?
>> UM...NO, NOT AT ALL.
Meredith: NOT YET. ALL RIGHT.
WELL, YOUR OWN BASIC KNOWLEDGE
IS CERTAINLY PAYING OFF.
$30,000 IN YOUR BANK AT THIS
POINT, 10 AWAY FROM A MILLION.
YOU STILL HAVE TWO LIFELINES
LEFT. YOU READY TO KEEP PLAYING?
>> I'M READY.
Meredith: THEN LET'S PLAY.
IN THE HOLIDAY CAROL "THE 12
DAYS OF CHRISTMAS," HOW MANY
DIFFERENT BIRDS DOES THE SINGER
RECEIVE ON THE FINAL DAY? 15,
19, 23, 28.
>> A PARTRIDGE IN A PEAR TREE.
TWO TURTLE DOVES. 3.
3 FRENCH HENS. 6.
4 LORDS A-LEAPING. 5 LADIES
DANCING. SOMEONE'S MILKING.
SO I'M UP TO 6. 6...
WAIT. ♪ 5 GOLDEN RINGS  SO
THOSE ARE OUT. HEH! 6 MAIDS
A-MILKING. 7...SOMETHING
SWIMMING. MAN, IT'S HARD TO DO
BACKWARDS. 12...UGH.
Meredith: HOW MANY ARE YOU UP
TO? WHAT HAVE YOU GOT IN YOUR
HANDS?
>> IT'S THE PARTRIDGE IN THE
PEAR TREE, IT'S 3 FRENCH HENS,
TWO TURTLE DOVES--3, 5, 6--8
GEESE A-LAYING. OOH, 8 GEESE.
PARTRIDGE IN A PEAR TREE, TWO
TURTLE DOVES IS 3. 3 FRENCH
HENS IS 6. 8 GEESE A-LAYING IS
14. [SIGH]
I'M GONNA ASK THE AUDIENCE.
Meredith: OK, AUDIENCE, RYAN
NEEDS YOUR HELP. ON YOUR
KEYPADS, VOTE NOW.
59% BELIEVE IT IS 23.
>> THAT'S A GOOD NUMBER, A
STRONG NUMBER.
WHERE WAS I? I WAS ONLY AT 6. I
WAS AT 14. 9. IT'S 9 SOMETHING.
THEY KNOW SOMETHING I DON'T.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
GOT TO GO WITH THE AUDIENCE.
"C."
Meredith: FINAL?
[SCATTERED LAUGHTER]
>> [SIGH]
"C," FINAL ANSWER.
Meredith: 7 SWANS A-SWIMMING, 6
GEESE A-LAYING, 4 CALLING
BIRDS, 3 FRENCH HENS, TWO
TURTLE DOVES, AND A PARTRIDGE
IN A PEAR TREE COMES OUT TO 23.
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
>> THANK YOU.
Meredith: SOME PEOPLE IN THIS
AUDIENCE CAN COUNT. YOU'D
BETTER GO LOOK THAT SONG UP
AGAIN, FOR SURE. OK, RYAN, HOW
MUCH MONEY IS BEHIND THIS
QUESTION?
7,000. $37,000.
>> AWESOME.
Meredith: ALL RIGHT, 9 AWAY
FROM A MILLION. YOU STILL HAVE
A LIFELINE LEFT AND SOME BIG
MONEY AS WELL. BECAUSE OF THE
SPECIES OF ITS MASCOT, WHEN
TARGET'S WEBSITE CRASHES, IT
OFTEN DISPLAYS WHAT WORD ON ITS
ERROR SCREEN? WOOF, QUACK,
MEOW, MOO.
>> ALL RIGHT, THE MASCOT OF
TARGET IS A WHITE DOG WITH A
RED TARGET ON ITS EYE. IT'S A
DOG. WOOF. "A."
FINAL ANSWER.
Meredith: YEAH, WOOF. THE
MASCOT IS A DOGGIE. COULD BE
SOME BIG MONEY BEHIND THIS
QUESTION. LET'S TAKE A LOOK.
HOW MUCH MONEY ARE WE ADDING TO
RYAN'S BANK? WE'RE GONNA PUT IN
ANOTHER $15,000. RYAN'S UP TO
$52,000. WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK
WITH MORE "MILLIONAIRE."
Meredith: WE ARE BACK WITH RYAN
CARLIN FROM ELKINS PARK,
PENNSYLVANIA. $52,000 IN YOUR
BANK. THAT'S A LOT OF MONEY.
RIGHT NOW, YOU'RE UNEMPLOYED.
I'M SURE YOU COULD PROBABLY USE
IT.
>> THIS HELPS.
Meredith: COMES IN HANDY,
ABSOLUTELY. 4 AWAY FROM ROUND
TWO. AT THAT POINT, YOU GET TO
KEEP ALL THE MONEY IN THE BANK,
AND THERE'S STILL SOME GOOD
MONEY ON THE BOARD, INCLUDING
THE $10,000, AND YOU HAVE A
LIFELINE LEFT. YOU READY TO
KEEP PLAYING?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
Meredith: THEN LET'S PLAY.
ANGRY OVER THEIR GOVERNMENT'S
FINANCE POLICIES, IN 2011,
PROTESTERS IN WHAT COUNTRY
STARTED HURLING YOGURT AT
POLICE? PORTUGAL, IRELAND,
ITALY, GREECE.
>> THE COUNTRY THAT HAS THE
WORST FINANCIAL SHAPE OF THE 4
IS GREECE, WITHOUT A DOUBT.
IRELAND'S IN NOT GREAT SHAPE,
EITHER.
IT KIND OF APPLIES TO EVERY
COUNTRY NOW.
TO ME GREECE SEEMS THE COUNTRY
IN THE WORST SHAPE. THEY'RE IN
CONTINUAL--BUT HURLING YOGURT.
THE BANK IS 50...
Meredith: HAVE 52,000 IN THE
BANK. YOU STILL HAVE A JUMP. IF
YOU THINK YOU KNOW THIS, GO FOR
IT. MISS IT, THOUGH, YOU LOSE
YOUR BANK.
>> GREECE IS THE COUNTRY THAT'S
IN THE WORST FINANCIAL SHAPE OF
ALL OF THEM. IT'S CONTINUALLY
IN DEFAULT. "D," GREECE.
Meredith: FINAL?
>> FINAL ANSWER.
Meredith: YOU KNOW, YOU GO INTO
ANY SUPERMARKET NOW, AND YOU'RE
GONNA FIND SO MUCH GREEK
YOGURT, IT'S UNBELIEVABLE. IT
IS GREECE. IT'S ALL OVER THE
PLACE. IT'S THE HOTTEST YOGURT
RIGHT NOW. AND YOU ARE
ABSOLUTELY RIGHT. ALL RIGHT,
LET'S SEE HOW MUCH MONEY IS
BEHIND THIS.
$500. OHH. OK. DOESN'T MATTER.
3 AWAY FROM ROUND TWO. AT THAT
POINT, YOU GET TO KEEP ALL THE
MONEY IN YOUR BANK. $52,500.
10,000 IS STILL UP THERE.
"TAKING MEASUREMENTS." A
MARIGRAPH IS A DEVICE THAT
MEASURES WHAT?
LAVA TEMPERATURES, CLOUD
SPEEDS, TIDE LEVELS, TREE
CIRCUMFERENCES. A MARIGRAPH.
STILL HAVE A LIFELINE IF YOU
NEED IT.
>> I'M REALLY GLAD I SAVED THAT
JUMP. MARIGRAPH.
MARI...MARITIME? MARITIME IS
OCEAN. TIDE LEVELS.
CLOUD SPEEDS. THAT'S JUST WIND.
TREE CIRCUMFERENCES. THAT'S A
RULER. LAVA TEMPERATURES?
THAT'S A THERMOMETER. TIDE
LEVELS. MARIGRAPH. MARIGRAPH.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
[SIGH]
I CAN TALK MYSELF INTO ALMOST
ANY ANSWER, BUT I'M NOT GONNA
BE ABLE TO TALK MYSELF INTO
THIS. I DON'T KNOW WHAT A
MARIGRAPH IS. OBVIOUSLY I'M
LEANING TOWARDS ONE. IT'S
PROBABLY GONNA GLOW GREEN, BUT
I'M GONNA HAVE TO JUMP THIS
QUESTION.
Meredith: OK, YOU DON'T HAVE TO
ANSWER THE QUESTION. LET'S SEE
THE RIGHT ANSWER. YOU WERE
RIGHT. IT WAS TIDE LEVELS.
LET'S HOPE THAT THERE'S NOT
10,000 BEHIND THIS QUESTION.
SHOW US THE MONEY, PLEASE,
COMPUTER. OH. GOOD. YOU LOSE
100, BUT YOU JUMP OVER A
QUESTION, MEANING YOU'RE NOW
JUST 6 AWAY FROM A MILLION, TWO
AWAY FROM ROUND TWO, WHEN YOU
GET TO KEEP ALL YOUR MONEY.
"DEEP SECRET" IS THE CATEGORY.
FOR MANY YEARS, WHICH OF THESE
TV JOURNALISTS WAS SUSPECTED OF
BEING THE WATERGATE INFORMANT
KNOWN AS "DEEP THROAT"?
BARBARA WALTERS, DAN RATHER,
DIANE SAWYER, TED KOPPEL.
>> WELL, IT WAS COMMONLY KNOWN
THAT DEEP THROAT--WELL, AT
LEAST IN THE MOVIE--WAS A GUY.
SO THAT PUTS US TO DAN RATHER
OR TED KOPPEL.
[SIGH]
Meredith: YOU HAVE 52,500. IF
YOU CHOOSE TO WALK, YOU COULD
WALK WITH $26,250. GET THIS
RIGHT, IT COULD BE WORTH AS
MUCH AS 10,000 TO YOU, BUT IF
YOU MISS IT, ONCE AGAIN, YOU
LOSE THE BANK.
>> I'M THINKING IT'S DAN RATHER.
BUT I CAN'T RULE OUT TED
KOPPEL. IT'S A BIG GAMBLE.
BUT I CAME TO PLAY. "B," DAN
RATHER.
Meredith: FINAL ANSWER?
>> MEREDITH, I'M AFRAID--YOU
KNOW, I CAN'T COMMIT TO THAT. I
WANT TO. I REALLY DO. I'M
AFRAID I'M GONNA HAVE TO WALK.
Meredith: IS THAT A FINAL, RYAN?
>> THAT IS A FINAL.
Meredith: YEAH, I'M REALLY GLAD
YOU DID. THE PERSON WORKED IN
THE NIXON ADMINISTRATION. IT
WAS DIANE SAWYER. THAT WAS THE
ONE THAT PEOPLE SUSPECTED.
YOU'RE WALKING WITH $26,250.
GOOD JOB. YOU DID A GREAT JOB.
WE'LL BE BACK WITH MORE
"MILLIONAIRE" RIGHT AFTER THIS.
Meredith: HERE'S YOUR
MILLIONAIRE QUESTION OF THE DAY.
WHICH OF THESE TOURIST
ATTRACTIONS IS
NOT PROFILED IN THE 2003 BEST
SELLER "1,000 PLACES TO SEE
BEFORE YOU DIE"? STAY TUNED FOR
THE ANSWER, WHEN WE COME BACK.
Meredith: WELCOME BACK. THE
ANSWER TO THE MILLIONAIRE
QUESTION OF THE DAY IS
GATEWAY ARCH.
WE ARE ALMOST OUT OF TIME, SO
INSTEAD OF STARTING A NEW GAME,
WE'RE GONNA GIVE ONE OF OUR
AUDIENCE MEMBERS A SHOT AT
WINNING $1,000.
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
AND TODAY'S LUCKY AUDIENCE
MEMBER IS BOBBY ZIRINGER?
ZIRINGER?
HEY! BOBBY, HOW ARE YOU--MMM!
PLEASURE--MWAH! PLEASURE TO
MEET YOU.
>> YOU'RE SO BEAUTIFUL.
Meredith: OH, THANK YOU. H
ARE YOU, BOBBY?
>> I'M DOING GREAT.
Meredith: YEAH? TELL US ABOUT
YOU.
>> WELL, I HAVE 3 DAUGHTERS. I
HAVE A WONDERFUL WIFE, WHO'S UP
IN THE AUDIENCE, DONNA. 5
GRANDKIDS--I'M VERY PROUD OF
THEM. THEY'RE ALL DOING GREAT.
AND IT'S VERY EXCITING TO BE IN
PITTSBURGH--ER, IN NEW YORK.
WE'RE FROM PITTSBURGH, BUT
IT'S EXCITING TO BE HERE.
Meredith: YOU ARE IN NEW YORK.
YOU'RE ON THE STAGE, ON THE SET
OF "MILLIONAIRE."
>> WONDERFUL.
Meredith: AND HOPEFULLY YOU'RE
ABOUT TO WIN A THOUSAND
DOLLARS. OK? DOES THAT SOUND
GOOD?
>> WITH 5 GRANDKIDS, I CAN USE
IT.
Meredith: OK. LET ME TELL YOU
HOW THIS IS GOING TO WORK. YOU
ARE GONNA FACE THE NEXT
QUESTION THAT RYAN WOULD HAVE
FACED HAD HE NOT WALKED AWAY,
AND YOU GET IT RIGHT, AND AS I
SAID, YOU'RE GONNA WIN A
THOUSAND DOLLARS. SO ARE YOU
READY, BOBBY?
>> LET'S GIVE IT A GO.
Meredith: AUDIENCE, ARE YOU
READY?
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
LET'S PLAY "MILLIONAIRE." ALL
RIGHT, BOBBY, HERE IT IS FOR A
THOUSAND DOLLARS. ON YOUTUBE,
TEENAGE GIRLS MAKE "HAUL VIDEOS"
TO SHOW OFF THE RESULTS OF WHAT
ACTIVITY?
SHOPPING, WORKING OUT,
GARDENING, COOKING. HOW MANY
DAUGHTERS YOU SAY? 5 DAU--3
DAUGHTERS?
>> 3 DAUGHTERS AND 3
GRANDDAUGHTERS. 5 GRANDKIDS,
BUT 3 OF THEM ARE
GRANDDAUGHTERS. "ON YOUTUBE,
TEENAGE GIRLS MAKE HAUL VIDEOS
TO SHOW OFF THE RESULTS OF WHAT
ACTIVITY?" SHOPPING--THAT MAKES
A LOT OF SENSE. WORKING OUT.
GARDENING. I DON'T THINK TOO
MANY TEENAGE GIRLS ARE VIDEOING
THEMSELVES GARDENING. I DON'T
THINK THEY'RE SHOWING
THEMSELVES OFF COOKING TOO
MUCH, EITHER. AH...
I WAS TOLD THAT LOGIC PLAYS A
BIG PART IN THIS. I HOPE MY
LOGIC IS WORKING TODAY. I'M
GONNA GO WITH "A," SHOPPING,
FINAL ANSWER.
Meredith: LIKE I SAID, YOU'RE
IN NEW YORK CITY ON THE SET OF
"MILLIONAIRE," AND YOU JUST WON
A THOUSAND DOLLARS, BOBBY.
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
CONGRATULATIONS.
>> THANK YOU.
Meredith: CONGRATULATIONS.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH,
MEREDITH.
Meredith: LOOK AT THE CAMERA
OVER THERE AND SAY, "THANK YOU,
FOLKS. WE'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME."
>> THANK YOU, FOLKS. SEE YOU
NEXT TIME. THANK YOU, FOLKS.
SEE YOU NEXT TIME. THANKS,
ME[ Man ] WHEN YOU WANT TO GIVE
YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM SOME SUPPORT
TRY AIRBORNE!
WITH ZINC, ECHINACEA, GINGER
AND A BLAST OF VITAMIN C.
AIRBORNE. REAL IMMUNE SUPPORT.
Announcer: CLOSED CAPTIONING
SPONSORED BY...
[CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
DISNEY-ABC DOMESTIC TELEVISION]
[CAPTIONED BY THE NATIONAL
CAPTIONING INSTITUTE]
>> Announcer: THE FOLLOWING
IS A PAID PRESENTATION FOR THE
NUTRIBULLET, BROUGHT TO YOU BY
NUTRIBULLET, LLC.
[♪...]
>> ...MY MUSCLE ACHES,
MY BACKACHES REALLY STARTED
TO DECREASE SIGNIFICANTLY
IN ONE WEEK.
>> THE FIRST NIGHT THAT I
ACTUALLY USED THE NUTRIBULLET,
I ACTUALLY SLEPT REALLY WELL.
THAT WAS EXCITING.
THAT WAS PHENOMENAL.
>> THE BAD CHOLESTEROL, WHICH
WAS 290, WENT DOWN TO 190.
>> THE CHANGES THAT I SAW IN
MYSELF AND MY FAMILY
WERE JUST AMAZING.
>> Announcer: JOIN THESE PEOPLE
AND THOUSANDS JUST LIKE THEM AND
DISCOVER A MACHINE THAT FINALLY
HAS THE POWER TO TAKE YEARS OFF
THE WAY YOU LOOK AND FEEL.
LEARN FROM NUTRITION EXPERT AND
BESTSELLING TH