HI, SARA. SARA McIVER.
HI.
BOULDER, COLORADO.
WHAT DO YOU DO THERE?
I AM THE RECEPTIONIST
AT A PHYSICAL-THERAPY CLINIC.
I --
WHAT -- OH, I'M SORRY.
GO AHEAD.
NO, AND I'M
ALSO THE DIRECTOR OF MUSIC
AT A LOCAL CHURCH THERE.
I WAS GONNA SAY, MUSIC SOUNDS
LIKE YOUR LIFE. YOU SING.
YEAH. I DO, YEAH.
I JUST RECENTLY FINISHED
MY MASTERS DEGREE
HORAL CONDUCTING,
BUT I ALSO SING
ON THE SIDE.
THIS IS OPERATIC STUFF
AND CLASSICAL STUFF?
YEAH, I'VE BEEN
TRAINED CLASSICALLY,
LOVE TO SING OPERA,
AND I'VE KIND OF DABBL  IN .
THIS WILL SURPRISE YOU,
BUT I HAVE NOT BEEN
TRAINED CLASSICALLY.
NO WORRIES. SEE ME AFTER.
I'LL GIVE YOU A LESSON.
[ Chuckling ] OKAY.
NICE TO HAVE YOU HERE.
THANKS.
STACEY SWIMME FROM RIGHT HERE
IN LOS ANGELES, IT SAYS.
BUT I'LL BET
NOT ORIGINALLY.
NO, NOT ORIGINALLY.
I MOVED HERE FROM SAN FRANCISCO.
WELL, AT LEAST YOU STAYED
IN THE STATE, THERE.
ONE CHILD.
YES, I HAVE ONE BEAUTIFUL SON,
PARKER.
HE'S 10 MONTHS OLD.
YEAH.
AND, YOU KNOW,
YOU PUT THIS ON YOUR CARD,
AND I HEAR THIS
FROM A LOT OF PEOPLE WHO SAY,
YOU KNOW, THEY WATCHED IT
WHEN THEY WERE KIDS
WITH THEIR GRANDMA
AND ALL THAT STUFF.
YOU DID THAT, RIGHT?
I DID.
I WATCHED THE SHOW
WITH MY GRANDMA CAROL.
I KNOW SHE'D BE VERY PROUD
TO KNOW THAT I WAS HERE.
YEAH, WELL, I'M GLAD
YOU'RE HERE, FINALLY,
AND WE WISH YOU SOME LUCK.
THANK YOU.
YOU, TOO, MATT.
MATT URNESS, RIGHT?
YEP.
IS FROM CORVALLIS, OREGON?
THAT'S CORRECT.
GO BEAVS.
YOU'RE GOING TO SCHOOL?
YEP. I GO TO OREGON STATE.
GO BEAVS?
YEP.
YOU'RE GOING TYEP,HOOL?
I'M STUDYING BUSINESS.
YEP. I GO TO OREGON STATE.
YEAH,
AND HOW'S THAT GOING?
REALLY GOOD.
I'M ALMOST DONE.
ARE YOU
A REALLY GOOD STUDENT?
UH, I WOULD LIKE TO THINK SO,
YEAH.
GOOD.
I'M GLAD TO HEAR THAT.
YOU'RE NOT EVEN BEING
HUMBLE
BECAUSE IF YOU'RE GOOD,
YOU'RE GOOD.
AND YOU'RE A NEWLYWED?
I AM.
I'VE BEEN MARRIED
TO MY BEAUTIFUL WIFE, ALICIA,
FOR JUST A LITTLE WHILE NOW,
AND WE'RE HAVING
A REALLY GOOD TIME.
ARE YOU
A REALLY GOOD HUSBAND?
YES,
ALL RIGHT.
I LIKE TO CHECK
ON ALL THESE THINGS.
GET READY.
WE'LL DO ANOTHER "TOSS UP."
THIS ONE IS WORTH $2,000,
AND IT'S AN "OCCUPATION."
HERE WE GO.ADY.
WE'LL DO ANOTHER "TOSS UP."
[ BELL CHIMES ]
MATT.
VIDEO GAME
DESIGNER.
THAT WOULD BE IT, YEP.
GOOD JOB.
WHOO! YEAH!
ALL RIGHT!
JIM, YOU'RE AWAKE,
AREN'T YOU?
I CERTAINLY AM, PAT.
TONIGHT'S JACKPOT ROUND
UGHT TO YOU
BY SIMPLE GREEN
ALL-PURPOSE CLEANER.
MY NAME IS BRUCE FaBRIZIO.
IN 1975, I INVENTED SIMPLE GREEN
BASED ON THREE PRINCIPLES --
IT HAD TO BE SAFER TO USE,
IT HAD TO WORK,
AND IT HAD TO BE
COMPLETELY MADE IN AMERICA.
AND HERE'S
TONIGHT'S FEATURED PRIZE.
EXPERIENCE AN UNFORGETTABLE
FULLY GUIDED TOUR
OF THE GRAND CANYON
AND THE GREAT AMERICAN WEST
COURTESY OF caravan.com.
EXPLORE AMERICA'S
GREAT NATURAL WONDERS
AND ENJOY THE MYSTIQUE
OF MONUMENT VALLEY, HIKING,
A SCENIC BOAT RIDE,
AND MUCH MORE.
IT'S THE TRIP OF A LIFETIME,
AND IT'S ALL FROM caravan.com.
[ APPLAUSE ]
THAT LOOKS NICE.
"WHAT ARE YOU DOING?"
THE CATEGORY
FOR THIS FIRST ROUND.
AND THE FIRST SPINNER
WILL BE MATT.
ALL RIGHT.
G.
YES, WE HAVE G's.
WE HAVE ONE. WE HAVE TWO.
WE HAVE THREE.
I'D LIKE TO BY AN I.
UH-HUH. FOUR I's.
N.
YEAH, THREE N's.
ANOTHER $900.
SEE HOW EASY THAT IS?
COME ON. KEEP IT GOING.
THERE YOU GO.
S.
ONE S, YEAH.
I'D LIKE TO BUY A VOWEL.
MM-HMM.
E.
THERE'S ONE E.
SARA.
T.
YOU GOT IT. TWO T's.
I'D LIKE TO BUY A VOWEL.
.
AN A.
TWO A's.
OH, SARA. SARA.
STACEY.
[ SIGHS ]
R.
I'D LIKE
TO SOLVE THE PUZZLE.
OKAY.
SINGING ALONG
WITH THE RADIO.
YEAH.
[ APPLR.
HEY, NICE GOING.
THANK YOU.
ONE LITTLE-OLD SPIN, YOU GOT
$2,500, AND YOU HAVE THE LEAD.
BUT EVERYBODY
HAS SOME MONEY RIGHT NOW.
WE'RE JUSTAUSE ]  GETTI.
AND WE'LL BUILD
TO A CRESCENDO.
IS THAT A MUSICAL TERM?
YES. [ LAUGHS ]
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
TONIGHT'S
"AMERICAN HERITAGE" SHOW
IS BROUGHT TO YOU
BY THE FOLLOWING.
MY BLISS?
BLISTEX SILK & SHINE.
REAL SILK EXTRACTS,
WITH A TOUCH OF SHINE.
BLIDISCOVER BLISS.NE.
DISCOVER BLISTEX.
I HAVE HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE,
AND WHEN I GET A COLD,
I TAKE CORICIDIN HBP,
THE NUMBER-ONE
COLD BRAND
DESIGNED FOR PEOPLE
WITH HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE.
CORICIDIN HBP.
AND TONIGHT'S MYSTERY ROUND
WANTS YOU
TO MAKE HISTORY WITH CASH.
[ APPLAUSE ]
FUNNY HOW THAT ALWAYS
GETS THEIR ATTENTION.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
ALL RIGHT, EVERYBODY.
WE'RE LOOKING FOR
A "PLACE" THIS TIME.
AND SARA
WILL START THE SEARCH.
HERE SHE GOES.
R.
YEAH, TWO R's.
I'D LIKE TO BY A VOWEL.
UH-HUH.
E.
THERE ARE SOME E's.
ACTUALLY ONE E, AND HERE IT COM.
T.
TWO T's.
I'D LIKE TO BY A VOWEL.
A.
THERE ARE TWO A's.
OH, IT GOT YOU.
SORRY.
STACEY, YOUR TURN.
OH! I THOUGHT YOU WERE GONNA
MAKE IT OVER THERE.
SORRY. MATT.
AW! GEEZ.
ALL RIGHT, SARA.
THAT'S A PRETTY GOOD SPIN.
WHAT LETTER WOULD YOU LIKE?
S.
TWO S's.
$7,000.
I'D LIKE TO BUY A VOWEL.
UH-HUH.
O.
ONE O.
YOU CAN BUY ANOTHER
IF YOU WANT.
I WOULD, PLEASE.
I, PLEASE.
THERE IS AN I.
YOU CAN BUY ANOTHER IF YOU WANT.
[ LAUGHS ]
AND I'LL BUY A U.
YEAH,
THE LAST OF THE VOWELS.
THERE HAPPEN TO BE
THREE OF THEM, BY THE WAY.
NOW, SARA,
YOU HAVE $6,250.
I'D LIKE TO SOLVE THE PUZZLE.
WELL, GO AHEAD.
NATURAL HISTORY MUSEUM.
THAT'S CORRECT.
[ LAUGHS ]
HEY!
[ BOTH LAUGH ]
NICE GOING.
THANK YOU.
$6,250.
SHE'S UP TO $7,250.
AND WE'RE
ROLLING RIGHT ALONG HERE.
WE'LL LOAD
ANOTHER PUZZLE UP,
AND WE'LL COME BACK
AND SOLVE IT LICKETY-SPLIT,
AS WE USED TO SAY.
Vanna: CAN YOU SOLVE
THIS PUZZLE FROM 1999?
THE CATEGORY IS PLACE.
GET REWARDED FOR YOUR LOVE
OF MOVIES, MUSIC, GAMES,
AND EVEN V.I.P. EXPERIENCES.
JOIN SONY REWARDS.
REWARDING YOU FOR
WHAT YOU ALREADY LOVE TO DO.
LEARN MORE AT sonyrewards.com.
HERE'S THE CORRECT
PUZZLE SOLUTION.
WATCH TOMORROW NIGHT
FOR ANOTHER CLASSIC PUZZLE.
"PLACE" THE CATEGORY.
[ BELL CHIMES ]
THERE IT IS.
ALL RIGHT.
STACEY,
YOU'RE GONNA START THIS ONE.
ALL RIGHT.
HONKS ]
T.
THERE ARE THREE T's.
PICK UP THAT HALF CAR.
IT'S A CHEVY SONIC
THIS WEEK.
U HAVE THAT
AND $1,500,
IN CASE
YOU WANT TO BUY ANYTHING.
I WOULD LIKE TO BUY AN A.
WELL, THERE YOU GO.
THERE'S ONE A.
IN THAT CASE,
I'LL ALSO BUY AN E.
AND THERE ARE FOUR E's.
.         IN THAT CASE,
I'LL ALSO BUY AN E.
YOU KNOW, YOU MIGHT PICK UP
THAT OTHER HALF RIGHT AWAY.
[ HORN HONKS ]
S.
ONE S. PICK UP
THE OTHER HALF OF THAT CAR.
YEAH!
WELL, YOU KNOW
WHAT HAS TO HAPPEN NOW.
YOU HAVE TO
END UP SOLVING THE PUZZLE.
YOU CERTAINLY DON'T WANT TO
HIT ANY BANKRUPTS ALONG THE WAY,
SO WE'LL KEEP OUR FINGERS
CROSSED FOR YOU
AND ASK
WHAT YOU WANT TO DO NEXT.
I'D LIKE TO BUY AN O.
YES, ONE O.
ANYTHING ELSE?
I'LL ALSO BUY AN I.
YEAH, THERE AR I's,
AND ALL THE VOWELS ARE GONE.
N.
YES, TWO N's. PICK UP
THAT "GIFT TAG," IF YOU WOULD.
THAT'S $1,000
YANKEE CANDLE COMPANY GIFT CARD.
JUST PUT IT IN YOUR CAR.
THERE YO
STOP THAT WHEEL.
R.
YES, TWO R's.
$3,000.
F.
YES, TWO F's.
I'D LIKE TO SOLVE.
GO AHEAD.
RAIN FOREST
TEEMING WITH WILDLIFE.
THAT IS CORRECT. YEAH.
[ LAUGHS ]
YOU GOT EVERYTHING
THIS ROUND!
GOOD FOR YOU.
WOW! WHERE DO I START?
WHERE TART?
LET'S PUT
THESE TWO TOGETHER
AND SEE WHAT JIM THORNTON
HAS TO SAY ABOUT THIS.
IT'S THIS, PAT.
CONGRATULATIONS, STACEY.
THIS NEW CHEVY SONIC IS YOURS.
ENJOY THIS TOP SAFETY PICK
OFFERING REFINEMENT,
COMFORT, AND FUEL-EFFICIENCY.
SO MANY MILES, SO LITTLE GAS.
$14,660.
NOW, YOU COULD
TAKE IT WITH YOU,
BUT WE'RE GONNA
FLY YOU TO BELIZE.
YOU WON'T HAVE TO
DRIVE THERE.
OOH! WHOO! [ LAUGHS ]
HERE'S SOMETHING ELSE
YOU'LL LOVE, STACEY.
RELAX AND REJUVENATE
AT MARUBA RESORT JUNGLE SPA
IN BELIZE.
FOUND DEEP WITHIN
LUSH TROPICAL JUNGLES
AND ANCIENT MAYAN RUINS,
THIS EXOTIC ADVENTURE
OFFERS HIKING, SNORKELING,
AND WONDERFUL SPA TREATMENTS.
MARUBA DOES IT ALL.
SE ] [
WOW. THAT ROUND
WAS WORTH ALMOST $30,000.
APPLAUSHE HAS $31,380
ALTOGETHER.
[ APPLAUSE ]
THAT'S PRETTY GOOD.
OH, MY GOSH.
YEP. CONGRATULATIONS.
[ LAUGHS ]
WE'LL COME BACK IN A MOMENT
AND GIVE AWAY SOME MORE.
DON'T GO ANYWHERE.
SHE WON A CAR AND A TRIP.
[ APPLAUSE ]
Vanna: CLOSED CAPTIONING
SPONSORED BY...
CONSTIPATED?
YES.
SOME LAXATIVES LIKE DULCOLAX
CAN CAUSE CRAMPS,
BUT PHILLIPS' CAPLETS
N'T.
THEY HAVE MAGNESIUM
FOR EFFECTIVE RELIEF
OF OCCASIONAL CONSTIPATION.
EGULAR LIFE.
PHILLIPS'.LIVE THE REGU.
IT'S OUR THIRD.
IT'S A "SONG TITLE,"
AND IT'S WORTH $3,000.
[ BELL CHIMES ]
MATT.
"EIGHT DAYS A WEEK."
YOU'RE UP TO $5,000.
GOOD FOR YOU.
[ APPLAUSE ]
AND WE NEED A "PHRASE"
FOR THIS NEXT ROUND.
AND, MATT,
YOU'LL START.
T.D WE NEED A "PHRASE"
FOR THIS NEXT ROUND.
T.
ONE T.
I'D LIKE TO BUY AN E.
YEAH, THREE E's.
H.
TWO H's.
I'D LIKE TO BUY A VOWEL.
OKAY.
O.
S.
NO S. SARA.
YOU'RE ON A FREE PLAY.
Sara: A.
NOE'S NO A,
BUT YOU'RE ON A FREE PLAY,
SO THAT'S NOT A BAD PLACE TO BE
WHEN YOU CALL A WRONG LETTER.
AHA.
R.
ONE R. $5,000.
I'D LIKE TO BUWEL.
UH-HUH.
I.
ONE I.
THAT'S IT FOR VOWELS.
THEY'RE GONE.
Y A VOL.I.
YEAH, TWO L's.
I'D LIKE  TO SOLVE .
SURE.
THE WHOLE WIDE WORLD.
YEAH.
HI, HOW HAVE YOU BEEN?
I HAVEN'T SEEN YOU IN A WHILE.
YEAH, I KNOW.
ALMOST $6,000
THAT ROUND.
YOU'VE RACKED UP
$13,200.
STILL IN SECOND PLACE,
BUT GAINING SOME GROUND HERE.
AND WE HAVE TIME
FOR ANOTHER PUZZLE.
VANNA, DO YOU HAVE ONE,
BEFORE I OVER PROMISE?
YEAH, THERE IT IS.
[ BELL DINGS ]
AND THE CATEGORY FOR THIS ONE
IS "EVENT."
I'LL GIVE THE WHEEL
A FINAL SPIN
AND ASK YOU TO GIVE ME
A LETTER FOR THE PUZZLE.
YOU'LL HAVE THREE SECONDS
TO SOLVE IT.
VOWELS WORTH NOTHING.
WE'LL ADD $1,000 --
$1,500 A PIECE.
"EVENT" THE CATEGORY.
SARA, LET'S START WITH YOU.
A LETTER, PLEASE.
N.
FIVE N's. WOW.
THAT'S $7,500,
AND WHEN YOU SEE THE N's
AND VANNA'S OUT OF THERE,
YOU'LL HAVE THREE SECONDS
TO DO SOMETHING WITH THIS.
"EVENT."
[ BUZZER ]
STACEY.
G.
ONE G.
[ BUZZER ]
MATT.
Matt: L.
[ BUZZER ]
SARA.
A.
ONE A.
[ BUZZER ]
STACEY.
P.
NOPE. MATT.
F.
NO F's. SARA.
W.
ONE W.
WINNING AN ELECTION.
YEAH!
[ APPLAUSE ]
HEY!
I HAVE --
I HAVE SOME DEVASTATING NEWS
FOR THIS YOUNG LADY.
SHE IS NOT OUR WINNER.
SHE FINISHED IN SECOND PLACE.
ALL SHE HAS TO SHOW
FOR HER OUR HERE
IN CASH IS $22,200.
I'M SO SORRY.
PLEASE FORGIVE US.
I WILL. THANK YOU.
HEY, GOOD LUCK TO YOU.
THAT'S PRETTY GOOD
HALF-HOUR'S WORK, I WOULD SAY.
YOU CASHED IN
PRETTY NICELY, TOO.
I GUESS THERE WAS
A COUPLE OF "TOSS UP" WINS,
AND ENDED UP
WITH $5,000.
NICE JOB, MATT.
E.
THE WINNER!
SHE GOT A CAR.
SHE GOT A TRIP.
SHE GOT CASH.
SHE HAS $31,380.
SHE'S GOIN  CO
THE BONUS ROUND.
EVENTUALLY
THIS SENTENCE WILL END,
AND I CAN CATCH
A BREATH.
[ LAUGHS ]
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
G TOI CAN CATCH
A BREATH.
of Washington about the future
of Medicare and Social Security.
ANNCR: But you deserve straight
talk about the options on the...
table and what the for you
and your family.
ANCR: AARP is cutting through
all the political spin.
Because for our 37 million
members, only one word counts.n
Get the facts at earnedasay.org.
Let's keep Medicare...
and Social Security strong for
generations to come.
GO TO WALGREENS.COM.
JUST UPLOAD YOUR PHOTO,
CREATE ANY NUMBER OF GIFTS
AND PICK THEM UP
THE SAME DAY.
RIGHT HERE.
AT THE CORNER
OF HAPPY AND HEALTHY.
When we got married.
I had three kids.
And she became the full time
mother of three.
It was soccer, and ballet, and
cheerleading, and baseball.
Those years were crazy.
So, as we go into
this next phase,
you know, a big part
of it for us is that
there isn't anything on the
schedule.
WHEN A CONTESTANT
WINS THE BONUS ROUND,
MAXWELL HOUSE
WILL DONATE $2,500
TO REBUILDING ER
TO HELP COMMUNITIES IN NEED.
MAXWELL HOUSE
SELECTS THE FINEST COFFEE BEANS
FOR A DELICIOUS TASTE
THAT IS GOOD TO THE LAST DROP.
WELL, WELCOME
TO OUR LITTLE WHEEL.
THIS DOESN'T GIVE OFF
ANY RADIATION, DOES IT?
I'M JUST CURIOUS.
NO. APPARENTLY NOT.
YOU HAVE OVER $31,000
IN CASH AND PRIZES, AS YOU KNOW.
SHE'S HAPPY.
WHO'S OUT IN THE AUDIENCE
WITH YOU?
Stacey:
MY WONDERFUL BOYFRIEND, DON.
OH! I THOUGHT -- SENSED A COMMA,
AND THAT WAS THE END.
IT PERIOD.
HI, DON.
ALL RIGHT, SPIN THE WHEEL.
AND THERE WE GO.
GRAB THAT FOR ME, PLEASE.
THANK YOU.
AND COME ON ALONG,
WE'RE GONNA GO RIGHT OVER HERE.
AND YOU'RE GONNA STOP
RIGHT THERE.
OKAY.
NOW, THE CATEGORY TONIGHT
IS "PLACE."
YOU KNOW THE LETTERS --
R, S, T, L, N, E.
WE START WITH THOSE,
AS ALWAYS.
[ BELL DINGS ]
SOMETIMES IT DINGS
MORE THAN THAT, BUT THAT'S ALL.
WOW. OKAY, WELL,
YOU'RE OBVIOUSLY GONNA NEED
A LITTLE MORE THAN THAT.
LET'S HAVE THREE MORE
CONSONANTS, ONE MORE VOWEL.
H.
ONE.
D.
TWO.
M.
AND A VOWEL.
A.
THREE OF THE FOUR LETTERS
ARE IN THE PUZZLE.
SO THAT'S GOOD NEWS.
WE'LL SEE.
WE'LL ASK OUR AUDIENCE
TO BE VERY QUIET
AS WE GO THROUGH THIS.
ALL RIGHT,
IT'S A "PLACE."
YOU HAVE 10 SECONDS
TO TRY TO WORK THAT OUT.
GOOD LUCK.
HIDEAWAYS.
HIDEAWAY.
OUR HIDEAWAY.
LAND HIDEAWAY.
TROPICAL HIDEAWAY.
CUBAN HIDEAWAY.
[ BUZZER ]
YEAH,
YOU DID ALL YOU COULD.
AND THEY WERE ALL COZY.
OHH, COZY.
YEAH.
GEEZ.
I'M SORRY.
IT WOULD HAVE BEEN NICE TO HAVE
THAT C UP THERE TO HELP YOU OUT.
OHH!
WELL, YOU KNOW, I THINK
SHE DID FINE WITHOUT THIS.
$31,380 CASH AND PRIZES.
NICE JOB, STACEY.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK!
.
ACCOMMODATIONS PROVIDED BY
CROWNE PLAZA CINCINNATI NORTH,
HOME OF CoCo KEY WATER RESORT,
LOCATED IN CINCINNATI, OHIO.
OUR HOTEL PROVIDES
1,500 SQUARE FEET
OF MEETING SPACE,
ALONG WITH 257
NEWLY RENOVATED GUEST ROOMS.
CALL US
TO BOOK YOUR NEXT TODAY.
Vanna: IT PAYS TO BE
A WHEEL WATCHERS CLUB MEMBER.
WE'RE GIVING AWAY 5K EVERY DAY.
IF THIS IS
YOUR SPIN I.D. NUMBER --
DT4663737 --
CONGRATULATIONS!
YOU'VE WON $5,000
JUST FOR WATCHING "WHEEL"!
VE 24 HOURS TO LOG ON
TO wheeloffortune.com
AND CLAIM YOUR $5,000!
I WILL FIGURE IT OUT.
WELL, YOU KNOW, WE TALK ABOUT --
WORDS ARE OUR LIVES.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
CONTINUOUSLY VERSUS CONTINUALLY.
YES.
AND YOU THINK
YOU KNOW THE DIFFERENCE?
THEY'RE TWO SEPARATE WORDS.
YES.
WE HAVE CONTINUALLY
BEEN ON THE AIR FOR 30 YEARS.
RIGHT.
JOHN KENNEDY'S GRAVE SITE,
THAT FLAME,
HAS BEEN CONTINUOUSLY BURNING
FOR YEARS AND YEARS.
SO IF IT NEVER STOPS,
IT'S CONTINUOUS.
WE STOP BECAUSE OCCASIONALLY
WE HAVE TO SLEEP
AND STUFF LIKE THAT.
RIGHT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
SEE?
DOES THAT MAKE SENSE?
PROFESSOR WHITE HAS SPOKEN.
WE'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME.
BYE!
[ APPLAUSE ]
PROMOTIONAL CONSIDERATION
PROVIDED BY...
Announcer:
GRAB A BOX OF STEAK-UMMS.
ADD EGGS FOR BREAKFAST
OR A WRAP FOR LUNCH.
TRY A CHEESE STEAK ON A ROLL.
YOUR TASTE. YOUR STEAK-UMM!
THE ALL-AMERICAN BURGER BUSTER.
STEAK-UMM SLICED STEAKS.
FRESH HERBS MAKE THE DIFFERENCE
IN COOKING MY HOMEMADE DISHES.
NOW I CAN GET THEM ALL YEAR,
WITH THE GOURMET
CHIA HERB GARDEN.
IT CONTAINS EVERYTHING YOU NEED
TO GROW FRESH HERBS
RIGHT IN YOUR OWN KITCHEN.
ST SPRINKLE ON THE HERB SEEDS,
WATER, AND WATCH IT GROW.
KEEP THEM GROWING
IN YOUR KITCHEN
OR TRANSPLANT THEM OUTDOORS.
I BOUGHT ONE FOR MY MOTHER,
MY FRIEND, AND MYSELF.
MAKES A GREAT GIFT.
-- Captions by VITAC --
www.vitac.com
[ APPLAUSE ]
HAWKES, WE NEED COVER!
NO!
WHY DO YOU FEEL
AS THOUGH YOU CAN CONTROL
WHAT OTHER PEOPLE DO?
AAH!
NOW I WILL TAKE THE PAIN AWAY.
(groaning)
(gunfire, screaming)
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
YOU ARE NOW PRISONERS
OF THE PAKISTANI NAVY.
(gunshot, screaming)
(mutters)
(screaming)
PAUL!
(cries) YOU SAVED ME.
GO.
(gunfire)
(grunts)
CHRISTINE!
SAM!
WHERE YOU TAKING HER?!
NO! YOU ARE NO GOOD
TO HER DEAD. COME ON!