THINGS. I DON'T KNOW WHY. WHEW.
>> FROM EXOTIC WONDERS--
I CAN'T BELIEVE I CAN HARDLY
BREATHE UP HERE.
TO MY OWN BLOOPERS AND BLUNDERS.
THIS FEELS LIKE A SHOWER.
YOU'LL SEE ALL THAT AND MORE ON
TODAY'S "WILD COUNTDOWN."
WE TRIED TO LEAVE OUR TENTS,
NOT EVEN TO GO GET DINNER.
WE COULDN'T GET TO DINNER.
THE LIONS WERE EVERYWHERE!
GOLLY DANG!
[DOG BARKING]
WHOO!
HELP!
A DOLPHIN, RIGHT THERE!
HOLY MACKEREL!
JUST LIKE MY LIFE IS DEVOTEDTO A
TO THE ANIMAL WORLD, NATIONWIDE
INSURANCE IS DEVOTED TO THEIR
CUSTOMERS, PROTECTING WHAT IS
IMPORTANT AT EVERY STAGE OF
THEIR LIVES. THAT'S WHY
NATIONWIDE AND I HAVE BEEN
PARTNERS FOR OVER 30 YEARS.
LEARN MORE ABOUT NATIONWIDE
INSURANCE AT NATIONWIDE.COM.
[INDISTINCT TALKING]
WE'RE LOOKING AT 7 OF MY MOST
EXTREME DESTINATIONS IN SEARCH
OF AMAZING ANIMALS.
FIRST, AN AFRICAN DROUGHT. I
SURE WISH I COULD HAVE BROUGHT
A COUPLE OF ICEBERGS WITH ME TO
KENYA.RK IS A WILDLIFE
LAKE NAKURU PARK IS A WILDLIFE
SANCTUARY IN CENTRAL KENYA,
RIGHT ON THE EQUATOR.
LOOK AT THE CAMELS, SUE.
>> I CAN'T BELIEVE IT. I'VE BEEN
BLOCKED BY CATTLE BEFORE, BUT
NEVER A CAMEL ROADBLOCK.
>> THE LOCAL CATTLE WAS HAVING
DIFFICULTY SURVIVING A MASSIVE
DROUGHT. SO KENYANS BROUGHT IN
CAMELS AND GOATS, WHICH CAN
WITHSTAND THESE CONDITIONS VERY
WELL. I SURE WISH I COULD.
WELL, I DON'T KNOW HOW THEY
DO IT OUT HERE, YOU KNOW IT?
UGH.
>> YOU JUST WONDER WHERE THEY
GET THEIR WATER.
>> SOON WE FOUND A GOOD REASON
TO BRAVE THE HOT SUN.
OH, WAIT, WAIT. LOOK AT THIS,
SUE. LOOK AT--WAIT, WAIT.
>> OH, NO.
>> LET ME GET OUT. CAN I GET OUT
AND LOOK AT THEM?
>> OH, JACK.
>> I'M SORRY, I HAVE TO GET OUT
AND LOOK AT THEM.
>> OH, MY GOSH.
>> COME HERE, SUE. LET'S GO. I
GOTTA LOOK AT THESE.
>> OH, LOOK HOW CUTE. OH. AW,
THERE'S THE MOM.
>> GO AHEAD.
>> SHE'S COMING BACK FOR THEM.
>> HERE! COME HERE!
>> CAN WE JUST SEE THEM FOR
A SECOND? YOU WANT YOUR MAMA?
HERE YOU GO.
>> THERE YOU GO.>> AWW.
>> AWW.
>> YOU CAN TELL. SEE THAT
AFTERBIRTH? SHE JUST HAD THEM.
>> HOW OLD DO YOU THINK THEY
ARE?
>> ABOUT TWO DAYS. KEEP GOING,
BUDDY!
ONCE THE GOATS MOVED ON, WE DID,
TOO, CROSSING THE EQUATOR. AND
FINALLY, WE MADE IT TO LAKE
NAKURU NATIONAL PARK.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
SOON AFTER ARRIVING, WE GOT TO
SPEND TIME WITH SOME OF
THE EXOTIC BIRDS NAKURU IS KNOWN
FOR. SOME BIRDS DON'T MIND
THE HOT CLIMATE, AND I FOUND
A MILLION OF THEM. FLAMINGOS.
LAKE NAKURU'S UNUSUAL CHEMICAL
COMPOSITION MAKES IT AN IDEAL
OR THE PINK
BIRDS. IT SMELLS FISHY AND
ROTTEN TO ME, BUT TO FLAMINGOS,
IT'S HOME SWEET HOME.
LAKE NAKURU IS A VERY SALTY,
ALKALINE LAKE, AND THE FLAMINGOS
CAN THRIVE HERE. THERE'S ALLLGAP
KINDS OF ALGAE AND CERTAIN TYPES
OF LITTLE MOLLUSKS AND THINGS
THAT THESE FLAMINGOS CAN EAT.
THEIR CURVED BEAKS ARE SPECIALLY
ADAPTED TO SCOOP UP FOOD FROM
THE WATER. IN SOME HABITATS
THAT CAN INCLUDE INSECTS AND
SHELLFISH, BUT AT LAKE NAKURU,
THE MAIN DISH IS BLUE-GREEN
ALGAE.
RARE BIRDS, DRAMATIC VISTAS, AND
FRIENDLY PEOPLE. THE ROAD TO
THIS DESTINATION WAS HARD, BUT
LAKE NAKURU WAS EASY TO LOVE.
THE ARCTIC IS ONE OF THE COLDEST
AND MOST BEAUTIFUL PLACES ON
EARTH. TO SEE IF I COULD CUT IT
AT THE TOP OF THE WORLD, I
PACKED MY WARMEST SOCKS AND
CAUGHT A RIDE NORTH. AND I
BROUGHT A LONG PLENTY OF HOT
CHOCOLATE. SORRY, WILBUR, YOU
JUST GET A BANANA.
ON THE NORTH COAST OF BAFFIN
ISLAND, CHISELED INTO THE BOTTOM
OF A RUGGED MOUNTAIN RANGE, IS
THE SMALL CITY OF ARCTIC BAY.
TO GET A FEEL FOR THE PEOPLE AND
CULTURE OF THIS REGION, I TOOK
A VEN MAIN
STREET.
HELLO.
AND WARMED UP WITH SOME VERY
ANINES.
[HOWLS] I DON'T KNOW WHAT THIS
MEANS IN SLED DOG TALK, BUT--
[HOWLS]
ONCE I WAS READY TO BRAVE
THE ARCTIC WILDERNESS, I TOLD MY
GUIDE I'D PAY TOP DOLLAR FOR
A TOUR ON HIS SKI-DOO.
HEY, BY THE WAY, HOW MUCH IS IT?
WHEN YOU TRAVEL IN THE ARCTIC,
AVEL IS BY DOG
SLED OR SKI-DOO. WE GO ABOUT
20 MILES AN HOUR OUT HERE. NOT
BAD.
COME ON, LET'S RACE! COME ON!
THE BREATHTAKING LANDSCAPE SOON
GAVE WAY TO BITTER COLD--MINUS
25 DEGREES FAHRENHEIT AND
FALLING. FOR INDIGENOUS
CANADIANS, THE COLDER IT IS,
THE MORE THEY SEEM TO THRIVE.
BACK AT ARCTIC BAY, I MET
SIMEON, A LOCAL INUIT STUDYING
THE CULTURE OF HIS ANCESTORS WHO
SETTLED THIS AREA MORE THAN
4,000 YEARS AGO.
SO, YOU REALLY RELY ON
THE ANIMAL WORLD. I MEAN, IT'S
YOUR LIFE HERE.
>> WELL, OUR INTERCONNECTEDNESS
TO THE ANIMALS IS VERY
IMPORTANT, AS WELL AS
THE SPIRITUAL CONNECTIONS IN
RESPECTING THE LAND AND
THE ENVIRONMENT.
>> UP HERE, SNOW CAN ACTUALLY
WARM YOU UP.
SIMEON SHOWED ME HOW IN A REAL,
HONEST-TO-GOODNESS IGLOO.
>> YOU'LL SEE THE BIGGEST
DIFFERENCE IN TEMPERATURE ONCE
WE GO IN.
>> YEAH, IT'S PROBABLY LIKE
AN ICE BOX.
IT IS WARMER IN HERE.
>> YEAH, USUALLY IT'S ABOUT
10 TO 12 DEGREES WARMER THAN
OUTSIDE.
DAY!
>> 'CAUSE OF THE SNOW IS
A REALLY GOOD INSULATOR.
>> I CAN'T BELIEVE I'M IN A REAL
IGLOO. I BROUGHT SOME FOOD FOR
US. WE SETTLED DOWN FOR
AS WE SETTLED DOWN FOR LUNCH, I
REALIZED THERE WERE PREDATORS
OUT THERE THAT MIGHT WANT TO
TAKE A BIG BITE OUT OF US.
ARE WE SAFE FROM POLAR BEARS IN
HERE?
>> SOMETIMES YOU ARE, BUT THEY
CAN BREAK THROUGH. THEY'RE
LOOKING FOR SEALS, SO THIS IS '
MUCH LIKE A SEAL'S DEN.
>> THEY CAN BREAK THROUGH HERE?
>> OH, YES.
>> NO, I THINK WE'RE GOING TO GO
STAY SOMEWHERE ELSE FOR
THE NIGHT.
AND SO MY TOUR ENDED THE WAY IT
BEGAN--BRAVING THE ELEMENTS AND
DREAMING OF HOT CHOCOLATE.
COMING UP--
>> MMM.
>> HOPE A PENGUIN DIDN'T COME
BY.
PLUS THE BLOOPER OF THE WEEK.
NEXT, ON "WILD COUNTDOWN."
WE SET SAIL
ABOARD SeaWorld ONE
TO ENCOUNTER FANTASTICAL
SEA CREATURES AND STUFF,
WHEN SUDDENLY...
SHAMU OF THE SEA RISES AND
THE OCEAN CRASHES OVER THE BOW
WHEN OUR SONAR DETECTED
A TURTLE WORLD.
SO I TOOK CONTROL
AND STEERED US THROUGH IT.
THEN A CURIOUS SEA CREATURE
APPROACHED, AND AS OUR EYES MET
WE WERE TRANSPORTED
TO A SRWATER CAVERN...
SeaWorld?
I THINK THEY LIKED IT.
[ Female Announcer ]
START YOUR ADVENTURES TODAY
AT Seaworld.com
AND FIND SPECIAL OFFERS.
♪
This holiday when Kmart
Shop Your Way members
check out, they
can win...
... a trip to
Universal Orlando Resort,
during our 30 Days of
Surprise Sweepstakes.
You could have a despicably
good time.
Or win lots of other
great prizes.
For moreOnly at Kmart.n visit
Shop Your Way .com
Only at Kmart.
SILVER SCnly at Kmart.
TO FLAT SCREENS...NS...
TWIZZLERIZE YOUR
ENTERTAINMENT EVERYDAY
WITH TWIZZLERS,
THE TWIST YOU CAN'T RESIST.
[ Female Announcer ]
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA BARS,
RICH DARK CHOCOLATE,
TOASTED OATS.
PERFECT COMBINATIONS OF
NATURE'S DELICIOUS INGREDIENTS,
FROM NATURE VALLEY.
♪
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA BARS,
NATURE AT ITS MOST DELICIOUS.
YOU SPEND ALL DAY COOKING IT.
SO WHY SPEND EVEN A MOMENT
CONSIDERING ANY BROTH
BUT SWANSON?
THE BROTH COOKS TRUST MOST
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
IN STUFFING AND MORE,
THE SECRET IS SWANSON.
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
she doesn't
Even though our really get us.
And she'll never know
who we are, or what...
No way,
Madden Girls??
Nike!
Who's your mommy now?s. Fal
Famous brands. Famously easy.
Famous Footwear.
Victory is Yours.
>> WELCOME BACK TO "WILD
COUNTDOWN." I'M JACK HANNA, AND
ON TODAY'S SHOW, WE'RE GOING
FROM THE AFRICAN EQUATOR--
LOOK AT THE CAMELS, SUE.GLOBE.
TO THE TOP OF THE GLOBE.
I CAN'T BELIEVE I'M IN A REAL
IGLOO.
SINCE I'M ALL BUNDLED UP FOR
, MAY AS WELL SHOW
YOU ANOTHER ONE OF MY FROSTIEST
ADVENTURES, THIS TIME AT
THE OTHER END OF THE PLANET.
WANNA GO WILBUR?
ANTARCTICA IS THE
WINDIEST, HIGHEST, AND DRIEST
CONTINENT. THAT SOUNDED LIKE
THE IDEAL HOLIDAY DESTINATION TO
MY DAUGHTER KATHALEEN, SO OFF
WE WENT TO PARADISE HARBOR ON
THE ANTARCTIC PENINSULA.
THIS TERRAIN IS ABOUT 98% SOLID
ICE AND 2% BARREN ROCK. WITH
AN AVERAGE TEMPERATURE OF MINUS
56 DEGREES FAHRENHEIT, IT'S
DEFINITELY NOT MY IDEA OF
PARADISE, BUT MILLIONS OF
PENGUINS THRIVE HERE.
>> LOOK AT ALL THESE ICEBERGS.
>> SOME OF THESE ICEBERGS
ACTUALLY LAST ANYWHERE FROM TWO
TO THREE YEARS.
>> REALLY?
>> YEAH, THE BIG ONES. THEY JUST
KEEP FLOATING ALL AROUND
ANTARCTICA.
THE ICE SHEET IS CONSTANTLY ON
THE MOVE. GLACIERS ARE PULLED BY
GRAVITY TOWARDS THE SEA, FORMING
GIGANTIC BLOCKS OF ICE ALONG
THE COASTLINE. WHEN PIECES BREAK
OFF, THEY FORM FLOATING
ICEBERGS. YOU EVER WONDER WHAT
AN ICEBERG TASTES LIKE? WE DID.
>> MMM.
>> BOY, I HOPE A PENGUIN DIDN'T
COME BY.
>> OH, THAT'S A GOOD POINT.
>> YEAH.
>> THANK YOU. THAT WAS NICE FOR
A MINUTE.
>> OK.
WE CAME TO VISIT IN THE SUMMER,
SO THE EARLY SNOW WAS
A SURPRISE, ESPECIALLY FOR
THE GENTOO PENGUINS AND THEIR
NEWLY HATCHED YOUNG.
KATHALEEN, CAN YOU BELIEVE IT'S
SNOWING AND IT'S SUMMERTIME IN
THE ANTARCTIC?
>> NO, IT MUST NOT BE GOOD FOR
THESE LITTLE GUYS.
>> NO, IT'S NOT GOOD AT ALL
BECAUSE SOME OF THESE ACTUALLY
ARE EVEN JUST HATCHING.
>> REALLY?
>> YEAH, AND WINTER'S SUPPOSED
TO BE HERE IN 4 TO 6 WEEKS.
>> SO I GUESS THE MOM AND DAD
THEN TAKE OFF?
>> WELL, YEAH, THEY HAVE TO GO
MOLT, AND THEN THEY HAVE TO
FATTEN THEMSELVES UP. AND SO
THEY HAVE TO LEAVE THE BABIES.
AND ONCE THOSE BABIES ARE LEFT,
YOU'VE GOT THE SKUAS AND ALL
THE TYPES OF BIRDS THAT ARE
GONNA COME DOWN AND--THAT'S IT,
THAT'S NATURE.
IT WOULD BE A HARD SEASON FOR
MANY PENGUIN BABIES, BUT
THE ADULTS WOULD DO JUST FINE.
FULLY GROWN, THE REMARKABLE
BIRDS HAVE A LAYER OF INSULATING
BLUBBER AND DOWN FEATHERS TO
HELP THEM WEATHER THE STORMS.
ANTARCTICA WAS NOTHING SHORT OF
SPECTACULAR. A DIVERSE CONTINENT
OF ICE MOUNTAINS, FROZEN
DESERTS, AND SOME OF THE EARTH'S
HARDIEST CREATURES.
NEXT UP, MY EXTREME UNDERSEA
TOUR OF THE CAYMAN ISLANDS.
LOCATED BETWEEN CUBA AND CENTRAL
AMERICA, THE CAYMANS MAY LOOK
TYPICALLY TROPICAL--
THAT WATER'S BLUE.
BUT BENEATH THE WATER'S SURFACE,
A WORLD OF EXTREME MARINE LIFE
AWAITS. INSTEAD OF PUTTING ON MY
SCUBA GEAR, I HEADED STRAIGHT
FOR THE SUBMARINE DOCK.
JUST LIKE IN THE MOVIES. WHOO!
WHOO! WHOO! THIS THING IS HEAVY.
I HOPE IT'S SEALED TIGHT.
THE SUBMARINE WAS A LITTLE
CRAMPED, BUT IT GAVE US
AN INCREDIBLE VIEW OF HUGE
TARPON AND GHOSTLY, NEARLY
TRANSPARENT JELLYFISH.
THE MOST DARING SCUBA DIVERS
REACH A DEPTH OF A COUPLE
HUNDRED FEET. I NEVER GO
PASSED 50 MYSELF. BUT THANKS TO
THE SUB, WE PASSED SEVERAL
HUNDRED FEET IN COMFORT, AND
EVEN GOT TO LOOK INTO THE DEEP
OCEAN BELOW.
>> NOW, BETWEEN THE ISLANDS WE
HAVE THESE REALLY DEEP VALLEYS,
THE CAYMAN TRENCHES. WATER THERE
IS THE DEEPEST POINT IN
THE CARIBBEAN.
>> ANYBODY EVER BEEN DOWN THERE
AT THE BOTTOM?
>> AS FAR AS I KNOW, IT'S
TOTALLY UNEXPLORED.
>> IT TAKES THE MOST ADVANCED
SUBMERSIBLES TO GO THAT DEEP.
MAYBE NEXT TIME.
I SURVIVED MY FIRST SUB RIDE.
WHEW!
COMING UP--
WE'VE BEEN WALKING FOR 8 MILES,
AND LOOK AT THESE STINGING
NETTLES.
PLUS THE BLOOPER OF THE WEEK.
NEXT, ON "WILD COUNTDOWN."
For months, I had this deep pain
all over my body.
It just wouldn't go away.
My doctor diagnosed it
as fibromyalgia,
thought to be the
result of overactive nerves
that cause chronic
widespread pain.
Lyrica is believed
to calm these nerves.
I learned Lyrica can provide
significant relief
from fibromyalgia pain.
And for some people,
it can work in as early as
the first week of treatment.
So now I can plan my days
and accomplish more.
Lyrica is not for everyone.
Lyrica may cause serious
allergic reactions
or suicidal thoughts or actions.
Tell your doctor right away
if you have these,
new or worsening depression,
or unusual changes in mood
or behavior,
or any swelling or
affected breathing or skin,
or changes in eyesight,
including blurry vision
or muscle pain with fever
or tired feeling.
Common side effects
are dizziness, sleepiness,
weight gain, and swelling of
hands, legs and feet.
Don't drink alcohol
while taking Lyrica.
Don't drive or use machinery
until you know
how Lyrica affects you.
With less pain,
I'm feeling better
now that I've found Lyrica.
Ask your doctor
if Lyrica is right
for your fibromyalgia pain.
PREGO?!
BUT I'VE BOUGHT RAGU FOR YEARS.
[ Thinking ] WONDER WHAT OTHER
QUESTIONABLE CHOICES I'VE MADE?
I CHOOSE DATE NUMBER 2!
WHOOO!
[ sigh of relief ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHOOSE TASTE. CHOOSE PREGO.
I NEED YOU.
I FEEL SO ALONE.
BUT YOU'RE NOT
ALONE.
I KNEW YOU'D COME.
LIKE I COULD STAY AWAY.
YOU KNOW I CAN'T DO THIS
WITHOUT YOU.
YOU'LL NEVER HAVE TO.
YOU'RE ALWAYS THERE
FOR ME.
SHH!
I'LL GET YOU
A RENTAL CAR.
I COULD ALSO USE
AN UMBRELLA.
FALL IN LOVE WITH
PROGRESSIVE'S CLAIMS SERVICE.
with hand-layered pasta,
tomatoes,
and real mozzarella cheese.
But what makes us even
prouder...
is what our real
dinners can do for your family.
Stouffer's.
Let's fix dinner.
[ Female Announcer ]
HOLIDAY COOKIES ARE A BIG JOB.
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE
JUST RIGHT.
PERFECTION IS IN THE DETAILS.
♪
GET TO HOLIDAY FUN FASTER
[FLAMINGOS SCREECHING]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
>> I'M JACK HANNA, WELCOME BACK
TO "WILD COUNTDOWN".
FROM ANTARCTIC ICE ISLANDS...
THAT'S UNBELIEVABLE!
TO THE BOTTOM OF THE CARIBBEAN
SEA, I'VE SEEN ANIMALS ADAPTED
TO THE MOST EXTREME HABITATS
ON EARTH.
NEXT UP, THE PRIMATES.
AND SOME GREAT ONES AT THAT.
TO REACH NUMBER THREE
ON TODAY'S COUNTDOWN,
I HAD TO TAKE THREE PLANES,
TWO TRUCKS, AND ONE BIG BOTTLE
OF ASPIRIN! AND HERE'S WHY...
UGANDA IS IN EAST AFRICA,
TWO WHOLE DAYS FROM
THE UNITED STATES BY AIR.
ALL RIGHT, UGANDA!
WE FINALLY MADE IT!
WE'D COME TO SEE THE HIGHLY
ENDANGERED MOUNTAIN GORILLAS,
BUT UNFORTUNATELY, THEY DIDN'T
LIVE ANYWHERE NEAR THE AIRPORT.
TO REACH OURBASE CAMPBASECAMP,
WE HAD A 200 MILE DRIVE.
WE DIDN'T MI
WE DIDN'T MISS A SINGLE POTHOLE
ALONG THE WAY.
EVENTUALLY, THE ROADS IMPROVED,
BUT WE STILL HAD A LONG WAY
TO GO.
HOW MUCH FURTHER?
>> WE HAVE ABOUT
THREE HOURS TO GO.
>> THREE MORE HOURS?
SEEMS LIKE WE'RE NOT EVER
GOING TO GET THERE.
A SUDDEN DOWNPOUR SLOWED US DOWN
EVEN MORE, AND I WAS STARTING
TO LOSE HOPE. BUT THANKFULLY,
THE WEATHER CLEARED UP IN
TIME FOR ME TO READ THE GOOD
NEWS--WE WERE ONLY A SHORT DRIVE
AWAY FROM GORILLA COUNTRY.
THE FINAL LEG OF OUR JOURNEY WAS
THE MOST CHALLENGING OF ALL-
HIKING THROUGH THE BWINDI
IMPENETRABLE FOREST.GH ENOUGH
GH ENOUGH JUST PULLING
MY OWN WEIGHT. GOOD THING
OUR INTREPID PORTERS CARRIED
THE HEAVY GEAR--
AND THEY WERE BAREFOOT!
LET ME SEE YOUR FOOT.
HARD LIKE SHOE LEATHER.
I MEAN, WE'VE BEEN WALKING
FOR EIGHT MILES IN JUNGLE WITH
THORNS. AND LOOK AT THESE
STINGING NETTLES, EVERYTHING.
I GOT HOLES IN ME, I GOT,
MY FEET HURT. IF HE CAN HIKE
THIS IS NO SHOES, I CAN HIKE IT
ALL THE WAY. LET'S GO.
INSPIRED BY MY HIKING PARTNERS,
I FINALLY REACHED
THE MOUNTAIN GORILLAS.
FROM THE LOOKS ON THEIR FACES,
THEY WERE AS CURIOUS ABOUT US,
AS WE WERE ABOUT THEM.
INTERESTED, BUT NOT HOSTILE.
EVEN THE POWERFUL MALE
SILVERBACK SEEMED PERFECTLY
COMFORTABLE WITH OUR PRESENCE.
IT'S JUST LIKE WATCHING A FAMILY
PLAY, ALL THE KIDS PLAYING
AROUND AND THE BIG FATHER
SITTING DOWN THERE.
AND THE MOTHER SLEEPING.
LOOK AT THESE KIDS PLAYING HERE,
LOOK AT THIS.
REACHING THE GORILLAS WAS
AN EPIC, EXHAUSTING JOURNEY.
AND YOU KNOW WHAT,
I'D DO IT AGAIN IN A HEARTBEAT.
THE NEXT DESTINATION ON TODAY'S
COUNTDOWN IS ALSO MOUNTAINOUS,
BUT IT'S ALSO A LOT CLOSER
TO HOME--MY HOME, IN FACT.
EVEN AFTER VISITING MONTANA
FOR MORE THAN 25 YEARS,
SUE AND I ARE STILL IN AWE
OF THIS MAJESTIC TERRAIN.
THERE'S NO SHORTAGE
OF
OF EXTREME DESTINATIONS
IN BIG SKY COUNTRY.
LIKE SUN RIVER RANCH--
3,000 ACRES OF WILDERNESS
AT THE BASE OF THE ROCKY
MOUNTAIN FRONT.
HOW'S THE WEATHER
FOR FLYING TODAY?
>> AWESOME.
>> SUN RIVER IS SO REMOTE,
MY WIFE AND I HITCHED A RIDE
ON A HELICOPTER TO GET THERE.
BELOW US WERE BOTH THE STUNNING
BOB MARSHALL WILDERNESS AREA
AND GLACIER NATIONAL PARK,
HOME TO THOUSANDS OF MIGRATORY
CREATURES LIKE ELK,
MOOSE AND DEER.
WELL, THE ANIMALS HAVE
A TREMENDOUS WAY TO MIGRATE BACK
AND FORTH IN THIS, YOU KNOW,
TENS OF THOUSANDS
OF ACRES ALL ON THIS FRONT HERE.
>> ALSO, WE'RE FLYING OVER
THE CONTINENTAL DIVIDE,
WHERE WATER ON THE WEST SIDE
GOES INTO THE PACIFIC OCEAN,
AND WATER ON THE EAST SI
ENDS U
ENDS UP IN THE ATLANTIC OCEAN.
>> SOME OF THAT WATER PASSES
THROUGH SUN RIVER RANCH,
SO OUR FRIEND LARRY WILSON
OFFERED TO TAKE US FLY FISHING.
CATCH AND RELEASE, OF COURSE.
HOW COME YOU DIDN'T TAKE THIS
BEAUTIFUL PLACE HERE AND LIKE
PEOPLE SELL OFF LIKE 20, 30
ACRES, AND LET PEOPLE LIVE HERE?
>> YOU KNOW, I'M INVOLVED
IN THE MONTANA LAND RELIANCE,
AND THEIR GOAL IN LIFE
IS TO PRESERVE THESE WIDE OPEN
AVE EASEMENTS
ON A MILLION ACRES
AND ABOUT 125 MILES OF RIVER.
>> SO, IN OTHER WORDS,
THIS PLACE WILL STAY JUST LIKE
THIS, EXCEPT FOR TTHAT ARE HERE.
THAT ARE HERE.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.S IN PERPETUITY.
IT'S IN PERPETUITY.
THIS WILL NEVER BE SUBDIVIDED.
>> COME ON, BABY!
THE FISH WEREN'T BITING,
SO INSTEAD, I CAUGHT THE EAR
OF GARY BERTELOTTI OF MONTANA
FISH, WILDLIFE AND PARKS.
WHAT IS IT WITH THE WILDLIFE
HERE, WHY IT'S SO PLENTIFUL?
>> WELL, SEVERAL REASONS--
ONE IS, THE ROCKY MOUNTAIN
FRONT GOES FROM UH, SUB ALPINE
DOWN TO THE PRAIRIES.
AND THIS IS THE ONLY AREANITED A
IN THE UNITED STATES THAT HASHES
PRESENT IN A VERY LITTLE AREA.
WE GOT GRIZZLY BEARS,
BLACK BEARS, ELK, MOOSE,
ALL THE DEER SPECIES, WOLVES,
BOBCATS, LYNXES.
SITY
OF HABITAT HERE.
>> CITIZEN CONSERVATIONISTS LIKE
LARRY VOLUNTEER THEIR TIME
TO PRESERVE THE WIDE OPEN SPACES
OF MONTANA. THANKS TO THEIR
EFFORTS, NORTH AMERICAN WILDLIFE
WILL HAVE A HOME HERE FOR MANY
GENERATIONS TO COME.
COMING UP...
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT,
I CAN HARDLY BREATHE UP HERE,
WE'RE ALMOST AT 14,000 FEET.
PLUS THE BLOOPER OF THE WEEK!
>> [COUGHS]
>> EWW.
NEXT ON "WILD COUNTDOWN".
[ Boy 1 ] Hey!
That's the last Crescent.
Oh, did you want it?
Yea
We'll split it.
[ Female Announcer ]
Made fresh, so light,
buttery and flakey.
That's half
That's not half!
Guys, I have more!
Thanks Mom
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Crescents.
Let the Making Begin
[ ding! ]
LOSING YOUR CHEX MIX TOO EASILY?
TIME TO DEPLOY
THE BORING-POTATO CHIP
DECOY BAG.
THEN NO ONE WILL WANT TO STEAL
THE DELICIOUSNESS.
[ Male Announcer ] WITH A
VARIETY OF TASTES AND TEXTURES,
ONLY CHEX MIX
IS A BAG OF INTERESTING.
[ Male Announcer ] WITH A
VARIETY OF TASTES AND TEXTURES,
OH, IT'S GREAT!
NOW I CAN BREW MY COFFEE
JUST THE WAY I LOVE IT.
HOW DO YOU DO THAT?
WELL, INSIDE THE BREWER,
THERE'S THIS TRAIN
THAT'S POWERFUL ENOUGH
TO CARRY MORE COFFEE
AND FRESH WATER TO MAKE COFFEE
THAT'S STRONGER
AND BIGGER...
AND EVEN HOTTER!
ACTUALLY, I JUST PRESS
THIS BUTTON.
BREW THE COFFEE YOU LOVE --
STRONGER, BIGGER, OR HOTTER --
WITH THE KEURIG VUE.
TO FLAT SCREENS...NS...
TWIZZLERIZE YOUR
ENTERTAINMENT EVERYDAY
WITH TWIZZLERS,
THE TWIST YOU CAN'T RESIST.
TO THE ANIMAL WORLD, NATIONWIDE
INSURANCE IS DEVOTED TO THEIR
CUSTOMERS--PROTECTING WHAT
IS IMPORTANT AT EVERY STAGE
OF THEIR LIVES. THAT'S WHY
NATIONWIDE AND I HAVE BEEN
PARTNERS FOR OVER 30 YEARS.
LEARN MORE ABOUT NATIONWIDE
INSURANCE AT NATIONWIDE.COM.
HI, I'M JACK HANNA AND WELCOME
BACK TO "WILD COUNTDOWN".
WITHOUT A DOUBT, THE FIRST SIX
LOCATIONS YOU'VE SEEN TODAY
HAVE BEEN SUPREMELY EXTREME.
NUMBER SEVEN,Y FLAMINGOES
OF KENYA'S LAKE NAKURU.
SIX, SLEDDING TO A BONA FIDERCT.
IGLOO IN ARCTIC BAY IN CANADA.
FIVE, SNACKING ON ICEBERGS
WITH MY DAUGHTER
AT THE SOUTH POLE.
FOUR, A SUBMARINE RIDE BENEATH
THE CARIBBEAN SEA.ROUGH
THREE, HIKING THROUGH
THE IMPENETRABLE FOREST
TO FIND THE ENDANGERED
MOUNTAIN GORILLAS.
AND TWO, MAJESTIC MONTANA,
A HOME WHERE THE BUFFALO ROAM.
FINALLY, A TRIP TO THE HIGHEST,
DRIEST DESERT IN SOUTH AMERICA,
WHERE I LEARNED ABOUT ONE
OF THE RAREST CATS IN THE WORLD,
JUST LIKE THIS SIBERIAN LYNX.
CHILE'S ATACAMA DESERT
IS EXCEPTIONAL IN EVERY WAY.
YET THIS ARID LAND SUPPORTS
A DIVERSE ARRAY OF WILDLIFE.
MY GUIDE NICO MELO KNEW THIS
REGION WELL, SO I WAS EAGER
TO EXPLORE THIS FORBIDDING
LANDSCAPE WITH HIM.
NICO, RIGHT?
>> YOU JACK?
>> YEAH! JACK HANNA.
FIRST, NICO TOOK ME HIGH INTO
THE MOUNTAINS, WHERE HE'D BEEN
RESEARCHING THE ULTRA RARE
ANDEAN CAT.
I CAN'T BELIEVE N HARDLY BREATHH
I CAN HARDLY BREATH UP HERE,
WE'RE ALMOST AT 14,000 FEET,
LOOK AT THIS PLACE.
>> IT'S A QUITE EXTREME
ENVIRONMENT, AND IT WAS
A SURPRISE TO FIND THIS CAT
LIVING HERE.
>> PHOTOS OF THE ENDANGERED
FELINE ARE ALSO RARE. BUT NICO
HAS CAPTURED SEVERAL IMAGES
USING A MOTION-ACTIVATED CAMERA.
HOW MANY OF THESE ANDEAN CATS
ARE UP HERE?
>> EH, WE'VE TAKEN A PICTURE
OF ONLY ONE ANDEAN CAT.
>> ONE.
>> YES. AND IT'S THE LEAST KNOWN
CAT IN THE WORLD, ALSO.
>> NICO WASN'T ONLY AN EXPERT
IN THE LOCAL WILDLIFE,
HE ALSO KNEW THE REMARKABLY
RESILIENT PEOPLE OF THE ATACAMA.
>> OK, JACK, NOW WE'RE GOING
TO MEET MRS. AYUDINA.
SHE'S ONE OF THE LAST SHEPHERDS
LIVING IN THIS TERRITORY.
SHE'S BEEN ABLE TO CREATE LIFE
AND SURVIVE IN SUCH HARSH
ENVIRONMENT.
>> LOOK AT THIS, I MEAN,
IN THE MIDDLE OF NOWHERE.
THIS IS UNBELIEVABLE.
>> HERE COMES MRS. AYUDINA.
EN SE LLAMA JACK.
>> TELL HER I LIKE HER DONKEY.'.
>> THAT'S HER CAR.
>> NO!
>> YES.
>> THAT'S YOUR CAR?
>> [SPEAKING SPANISH]
[LAUGHTER]
>> MISS AYUDINA'S SUPPLY WATER
CAME FROM A NEARBY CREEK,
WHICH HID DANGERS
I COULDN'T SEE.
>> IT CONTAINS ARSENIC.
>> ARSENIC?
>> ARSENIC.
>> LIKE THAT'S WHAT
KILLS PEOPLE.
>> YES.
>> AND I WAS GONNA GET READY
TO, 'CAUSE I WAS THIRSTY.
I'M GLAD YOU WERE WITH ME.
[NICO CHUCKLES]
[BLEATING]
>> THIS IS A VERY DIFFERENT WAY
OF LIFE, AND SOMETIMES DIFFICULT
TO UNDERSTAND FOR PEOPLE
WHO COME FROM A CITY.
>> YEP.
>> SHE HAS HER OWN SYSTEM.
AND WITH THAT, SHE'S HAPPY.
>> NOW IT'S TIME FOR MY BLOOPER
OF THE WEEK. OLD TITUS HERE,
HE LOVES SEEING MY MOST
EMBARRASSING MOMENTS.
ON A TRIP TO ISRAEL,
I CHECKED OUT A RUMOR I'D HEARD
ABOUT ALPACA--THEY SPIT
ON THE HAND THAT FEEDS THEM.
[LAUGHING] THIS FEELS LIKE
A SHOWER!
WHOO-WEE! THAT ONE GOT ME GOOD
THAT TIME.
[ Female Announcer ]
What would you call
an ordinary breakfast pastry
that's been wrapped
in a flaky crust
stuffed with a gooey center
toasted up all golden brown
then given a delicious design?
A toaster strudel.
Pillsbury Toaster Strudel.
So Delicious...So Fun.
And when I get a cold I take
Coricidin HBP.
The number one pharmacist
recommended cold brand
designed for people with high
blood pressure.
Coricidin HBP.
I HAVE TO SAY, I DON'T MIND
GOING TO THE EXTREMES TO SEE
AMAZING WILDLIFE.
IF YOU'RE FEELING ADVENTUROUS,
PICK YOUR NEXT DESTINATION
ON OUR WEBSITE,
WILDCOUNTDOWN.COM, OR FIND US
ON FACEBOOK, WILDCOUNTDOWNTV.
AND REMEMBER, NO MATTER
WHERE IT LIVES, EVERY CREATURE
COUNTS. ESPECIALLY MY PAL,
TITUS. FROM THE COLUMBUS ZOO,
I'M JACK HANNA,
WE'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME.
PROMOTIONAL CONSIDERATION
PROVIDED BY NATIONWIDE
INSURANCE, AND THE COLUMBUS
ZOO AND AQUARIUM.
JEFF: TODAY ON OCEANMYSTERI,
TRAVELING TO THE GREAT
STATE OF ALASKA FOR THE
ADVENTURE OF A LIFETIME
WITH THE MIGHTY STELLER
SEA LIONS.
WE'LL EXPLORE THE
COASTLINE OF AMERICA'S
LAST FRONTIER AND
UNCOVER THE SECRETS OF
THESE COLOSSAL MARINE
MAMMALS, FROM THE
SMALLEST TO THE LARGEST,
TO THIS GUY.
[SEA LION GROWLING]
♪ MUSIC