MARKET FOR ME AND HE IS KIND OF
BUSY RIGHT NOW.
WE ARE CHECKING OUT THE
PRODUCE.
I NEED TO GO DOWN AND SEE WHAT
IS AT THE MARKET AND SEE WHAT
THE NEXT SEASONS ARE LOOKING
LIKE AND I NEED TO STOP TALKING
AND HEAD DOWN TO THE MARKET
RIGHT NOW.
PRODUCE MARKET TIME IS WHERE IT
GETS EXCITING.
REALLY TRULY THE SEASONS ARE
DICTATED BY WHAT I WALK UP AND
SEE.
AM I GOING TO GRILL.
ROAST.
SERVE IS RAW.
SINCE JOE IS BUSY I HAVE A
CHANCE TO GO DOWN TO THE MARKET
AND SEE WHAT IS OUT THERE.
THIS IS REAL I GET REALLY
EXCITED BECAUSE I GET TO TASTE
AND FEEL AND EAT THE PRODUCE.
IS SF PRODUCE MARKET.
THE INSTITUTION IN
SAN FRANCISCO WHERE ALL OF THE
MARKETS ARE ALL TOGETHER AND
THIS IS WHERE I GO.
THIS IS WHERE I FIND THE BEST
STUFF AND I AM GOING TO SHOW
YOU EXACTLY WHERE IT'S AT.
COME ON.
♪
>>> SO IMAGINE JOE OR IMAGINE
MY SOUS CHEF OR MYSELF IN THE
KITCHEN.
WE NEED BLUEBERRIES AND
STRAWBERRIES AND THIS AND RENEE
WILL PUT THE THEM TOGETHER ANDE
DELIVERY TRUCK WILL SEND THEM
TO THE RESTAURANT.
WE LIKE TO TOUCH IT AND SEE
WHERE IT IS AT AND WHAT IS
GOOD.
THIS IS STONE FRUIT SEASON.
LOOK AT THIS.
SIERRA RICH.
THIS IS HOW DELICIOUS THIS
PEACH IS.
IT JUST SHOT EVERYWHERE AND
THAT IS WHAT YOU WANT.
FRESH AND GREAT.
YOU KNOW WHAT IS BETTER THAN
FRESH AND GREAT BESIDES GETTING
BEATEN UP BY A PEACH IS GOING
WHERE THE SOURCE IS AT.
YOU KNOW WHAT I THINK I'M GOING
DO.
TELL RENEE PUT THIS TOGETHER
FOR ME AND SEND THIS TO JOE AT
THE RESTAURANT.
I WANT TO KNOW EXACTLY WHERE IT
COMES FROM AND I AM GOING TO GO
STRAIGHT TO THE FARM.
>> OUT OF ALL OF THE PLACES TO
CHOOSE TO GO TO, ESPECIALLY
BEING A VALLEY BOY, MY PARENTS
AT ONE TIME WE HAD A WALNUT
FARM SO KNOWING PRODUCE AND
WHERE CANTALOUPES AND MELLONS
AND EVERYTHING COME FROM IS
KIND OF HOW I WAS RAISED.
THE FACT THAT THEY IN PRIME.
THEY DON'T PICK FOR QUANTITY,
THEY PICK FOR QUALITY.
WHAT YOU GET FROM FROG HOLLOW
IS THE BEST.
GO TO THE BEST AND SOURCE OUT
THE BEST.
IS WHERE I'M HEADED, I THINK.
♪
>>> ALL RIGHT.
HERE WE ARE ARE AT FROG HOLLOW.
EXCITED.
AND THERE IS THE MAN RIGHT RIGT
THERE.
HOW ARE YOU?
>> HEY, RYAN, WELCOME TO FROG
HOLLOW FARM.
>> EXCITED TO BE HERE AT THE
FARM.
>> BUT YOU ARE NOT
APPROPRIATELY DRESSED, RYAN.
>> WHAT IS WRONG WITH WHAT I'M
WEARING?
>> TRY THESE ON.
I THINK YOU WILL ENJOY THEM.
LOOSE AND COMFORTABLE FOR THE
HEAT.
A LOT OF POCKETS.
YOU CAN PUT THEM ON RIGHT OVER
YOUR CLOTHES AND THEY WILL
PROTECT YOU FROM THE DUST.
>> ARE YOU SERIOUS?
>> YEAH, DEAD SERIOUS US.
>> ALL RIGHT.
ARE THESE YOURS?
>> THOSE ARE MY OVERALLS.
>> I'M SO HONORED.
>> MAKE A FARMER OUT OF YOU
YET, RYAN.
>> AND ILE WEAR THE FROG HOLLOW
SHIRT?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> I WILL CHANGE AND WHAT ARE
WE GOING TO DO?
>> GO OUT AND PICK SOME FRUIT
AND THEN DO SOME COOKING IN THE
KIP.
>> I LOVE IT.
I'M EXCITED.
>> A FABULOUS MEAL.
>> I'M GOING TO DO THIS.
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> I'M GOING CHANGE.
>> FANTASTIC.
>> THE OVERALLS DON'T FIT
ANYWHERE ELSE BUT A CERTAIN
REGION AND GOT A LITTLE SNUG.
KIND LIKE A BIG 'OLE AIR
CONDITIONER.
IS THIS WHAT IT IS SUPPOSED TO
BE?
>> YOU LACK GREAT.
>> THEY ARE RIDING HIGH.
MY VOICE IS CHANGING OCTAVE
HERE.
I HAVE A QUESTION HERE.
YOU ROLLED YOURS.
>> OH, YEAH.
>> I ROLLED MINE.
SUPPOSED TO SHOW MY SOCKS?
>> YOU GOT TO WALK THE WALK,
RYAN.
>> I WILL WALK THE WALK.
I GOT ONE QUESTION FOR YOU.
IS MY WALLET SUPPOSED TO BE IN
MY KIDNEYS?
IT IS LIKE IN THE BACK OF MY
BACK HERE.
SO WE GOT A BIG 'OLE PIECE IN
HERE AND A CELL PHONE IN HERE.
>> THAT IS WHERE I GOT MINE.
>> YESTERDAY'S HUNDRED SEARCH
SIDE.ILUNCH IS ON THIS
>> THEY ARE KIND OF COMFY.
>> YOU STARTED THE FARM HOW
LONG AGO?
>> WHEN I WAS 28 YEARS OLD I
HAD THE VISION TO BECOME A
FARMER.
>> NOW, COVERED IN EVERYTHING
FROM APPLES OR PEARS?
>> PEARS, NECTARINES AND THESE
ARE PEACHES THAT WE ARE COMING
UP TO.
I WILL TEACH YOU HOW TO PICK
THE PEACHES.
THERE IS AN ART TO IT.
WE SPENT YEARS TRAINING THE
CREWS ON HOW TO PICK THE PEACH
AT PERFECT MOMENT OF RIPENESS.
RIGHT OFF THE TREE IS A MYTH.
>> REALLY?
>> EVEN IF IT IS DEAD RIPE IT
WILL STILL HAVE THE ASIDES THAT
COME FROM THE TREE.
>> OKAY.
>> AND THAT IS WHAT IS GOING TO
HAPPEN IF YOU LET IT AGE ON
YOUR KITCHEN COUNTER OR YOUR
DINING ROOM TABLE FOR FIVE DAYS
OR MORE.
>> SO THAT IS AN IMPORTANT
PROCESS OF EATING THE FRUIT IS
LETTING IT BE OFF THE TREE FOR
FIVE DAYS.
>> EXACTLY.
>> THIS IS THE TREE?
>> NEW YEAR'S THE TREES WE WILL
PICK, RYAN.
A -- THESE ARE THE TREES WE
WILL PICK, RYAN.
A LOT OF PEACHES NOW AADAYS
HAVE THE BEAUTIFUL CRIMSON
BURGUNDY COOLER TO ATTRACT THE
CONSUMER TO PURCHASE THE FRUIT.
WHAT YOU REALLY WANT TO LOOK
FOR THE TELLTALE SIGN OF
RIPENESS IS THE BACKGROUND
COLOR.
THE YELLOW.
A DEEPER GOLDEN COLOR
BACKGROUND IS WHEN THE PEACH IS
READY TO PICK.
>> THEY ARE LOOKING BACK HERE
TO SEE IT AS LITTLE YELLOW.
NOT AS GREEN.
THIS IS STILL A LITTLE UNDER.
>> DEFINITELY UNDER.
>> FIND ME ONE UNDER THE TREE I
KNOW WE STILL NEED THE FIVE
DAY.
FILM' LOOKING.
I WILL TEAK YOUR ADVICE HERE.
YOU SAID YELLOW AND NOT AS
GREEN.
I'M GOING TO GET THE FIRST ONE
THAT I LOOK AT AND LET'S SEE IF
I DID GOOD.
TALKING ABOUT THE YELL.
>> A BEAUTIFUL PEACH.
THAT'S PERFECT.
>> HERE IS THE $20.
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> SEE THE DEEP GOLDEN.
>> LITTLE HUE.
>> BACKGROUND COLOR. ARE LOOKIG
FOR.
>> DON'T EAT IT RIGHT OFF THE
TREE.
>> YOU CAN.
BITE INTO THAT PUPPY AND TRY
IT.
>> ALL I'M GOING TO SAY IS YOU
ARE GOING TO HUG THE FIRST
PERSON AROUND YOU BECAUSE THIS
FRUIT ALONE JUST IS LOVE.
IT IS JUICY, DELICIOUS AND
AMAZING.
IT IS KIND OF LIKE A HUG
MACHINE.
THAT IS WHY I HUGGED FARMER AL
AND HE MADE THE DAMN FRUIT.
I REALLY LIKE THE IDEA OF GOING
BACK AND COOKING AND HANGING
OUT WITH YOUR WIFE AND MAKE A
NICE LITTLE MEAL.
I DO NOT WANT TO COME ALL THE
WAY OUT HERE AND NOT HAVE A
TOUR OF YOUR FARM.
>> HOP IN THE LIMOED ON DO
THIS.
>> A SMALL LIMO BUT IT WILL
WORK.
I HAVE A PEACH IN MY POCKET.
I'M GOING ASK YOU TO GRAB THAT
ONE.
>> COMING UP, A TOUR OF FROG
HOLLOW FARMS AND I MAKE A
DELICIOUS PEACH CHERRY KIND OF
DRINK ALL STRAIGHT FROM THE
♪
>>> WHEN YOU DRIVE BY A FARM
YOU JUST DRIVE BY AND DON'T SEE
MUCH BUT TO SEE WHAT THEY DO
THERE AND TO SEE THE MAGNITUDE
OF WHAT IS BEING DONE FROM THE
REFRIGERATION PROCESS TO THE
BOXING PROCESS AND SEE THAT IT
IS ON YOUR TABLE FROM TREE TO
TABLE IN 48 HOURS WHERE DOES
THAT HAPPEN?
AN AMAZING BEAUTIFUL THING
HAPPENING THERE.
>> HERE WE ARE, RYAN.
THE DRIED FRUIT.
>> THIS IS LIKE DRIED FRUIT
HEAVEN.
TALK ABOUT HEALTHY, HUH?
>> THIS IS THE SUNCREST
VARIETY.
>> JUST LIKE THIS OUT IN THE
SUN.
>> YEAH, YEAH.
WE PEEL IT.
WE CUT IT IN HALF AND WE JUST
PUT IT ON THE DRYING ON A PIECE
OF WOOD.
>> I'M HAVING A MOMENT.
>> THIS?
>> TRUST ME.
>> I LOVE IT.
THIS IS JUST LIKE H HEAVEN OF
PEACHES.
LOOK AT THIS THING.
THIS IS AMAZING.
I LOVE IT.
I'M SO INSPIRED BY THE
SURROUNDINGS AND WHAT IS GOING
ON HERE.
WE WILL MAKE A LITTLE DRINK
INSPIRED WITH YOUR FRUIT.
I KNOW YOU HAVE TO GO MAKE SOME
MORE MONEY.
>> GO DO SOME WORK.
>> AND ILE MAKE A DRINK RIGHT
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE FARM.
>> AND I WILL HOOK UP WITH YOU
BACK AT THE HOUSE.
>> DONE, DONE AND DONE.
MY INSPIRATION BEING OUT HERE
ON THE FARM WAS TO MAKE A
DRINK.
I REGIONALLY WAS GOING TO DO A
CHERRY BASE.
PEACHES DRIED IN THE SUN.
BOUNTY OF A DRINK THAT HAS
AWFUL THE FRUITS HERE AT FROG
HOLLOW FARMS IN A DRINK.
KIND OF LIKE MY VERSION OF THE
LIMEADE.
I WILL TAKE THIS AND KIND OF
MUDDLE THE FRUIT.
THIS IS SUPER DELICIOUS AND
ALREADY RIPE.
HOPE YOU GUYS ARE LIKING MY
OVERALLS.
I'M WEARING THEM JUST FOR YOU.
ALL RIGHT, SO COME HERE.
CHECK THAT OUT.
RIGHT THERE ON THE BOTTOM.
I WILL TAKE SOME CHERRIES AND
TAKE THESE GUYS JUST LIKE THIS.
AND I'M GOING TO TAKE OUT MY
AGGRESSION.
BRUISE THE FRUIT UP A LITTLE
BIT AND WHEN I GET THE PERFUMES
IN THE LEMONADE.
CRUSH THIS UP.
THE KICKER A TRICK.
SIMPLY ONE PART SUGAR TO ONE
PART WATER.
THE SUGAR THAT GIVES IT THE
NICE LITTLE KICK, OKAY.
ADD SIMPLE SYRUP INSIDE HERE.
DON'T WANT TO ADD TOO MUCH
BECAUSE CHERRIES ARE SWEET AND
PLUMS ARE SWEET.
A LOT OF NATURAL SUGAR.
MIX THIS UP HERE AND ICE WILL
GIVE THE CHILL FACTOR OUT HERE.
ALL RIGHT, SO NOW I HAVE THE
CHIRRRIES AND PLUMS AND SIMPLE
SYRUP AND THE ICE.
I TOOK ALL OF THE CHERRIES AND
MADE A PUREE OUT OF IT.
MY SOUR KIND OF CHERRY I DRINK.
ADD CHERRY JUICE INSIDE THAT.
BEAUTIFUL.
AND A LITTLE BIT OF LIME JUICE.
THIS IS THE LIMEADE ASPECT OF
IT.
AND JUST BECAUSE I'M INSPIRED,
REMEMBER, BE INSPIRED FROM WHAT
IS THROUGHOUT.
A LITTLE BIT OF THE ROASTED
PEACHES INSIDE HERE.
CHERRIES.
AND BECAUSE I'M WEARING
OVERALLS IN THE MIDDLE OF THE
SUN FOR YOU GUYS I WILL DRINK
RIGHT OUT OF IT.
ALL RIGHT.
SO THIS ONE IS ALL FOR ME
BECAUSE IT IS HOT OUTSIDE AND I
WILL SIT UNDERNEATH THE TREE.
I WILL MAKE A FRESH ONE FOR
CHEF BECKY AND YOU WILL NOT
WANT TO MISS WHAT WE COOK OUT
THERE Y'ALL.
GET IT, OVER ALLS?
>> COMING UP I'M
I'M ONLY IN MY 60's...
I'VE GOT A NICE LONG LIFE AHEAD.
BIG PLANS.
SO WHEN I FOUND OUT
Medicare DOESN'T PAY
ALL MY MEDICAL EXPENSES,
I GOT A Medicare
SUPPLEMENT INSURANCE PLAN.
[ Male Announcer ] IF YOU'RE
ELIGIBLE FOR Medicare,
YOU MAY KNOW
IT ONLY COVERS ABOUT 80%
OF YOUR Part B
MEDICAL EXPENSES.
THE REST IS UP TO YOU.
CALL AND FIND OUT
ABOUT AN AARP Medicare
Supplement Insurance Plan,
INSURED BY UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company.
LIKE ALL STANDARDIZED Medicare
SUPPLEMENT PLANS,
IT COULD SAVE YOU THOUSANDS
IN OUT-OF-POCKET COSTS.
CALL NOW TO REQUEST
YOUR FREE DECISION GUIDE.
I'VE BEEN WITH MY DOCTOR
FOR 12 YEARS.
NOW I KNOW I'LL BE ABLE
TO STICK WITH HIM.
YOU'LL BE ABLE TO VISIT
ANY DOCTOR OR HOSPITAL
THAT ACCEPTS Medicare PATIENTS.
PLUS, THERE ARE NO NETWORKS,
AND YOU NEVER NEED A REFERRAL.
SEE WHY MILLIONS OF PEOPLE
HAVE ALREADY ENROLLED
IN THE ONLY Medicare Supplement
Insurance Plans
ENDORSED BY AARP.
DON'T WAIT. CALL NOW.
♪
>>> SO I'M AT FARMER AL AND
CHEF BECKY'S HOUSE AND I WILL
COOK UP GREAT DISHES WITH THE
FRUIT FROM THEIR FARM.
CHEF BECKY.
>> HEY.
>> HOW ARE YOU?
>> GOOD, HOW ARE YOU?
>> GREAT TO SEE YOU.
GUESS WHAT I MADE YOU.
MY VERSION OF CHERRY LIMEADE
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF PLUMS FROM
THE FARM AND THE DRIED PEACH
THAT ARE SUN DRYING OUT THERE.
I GRABBED THEM.
TELL ME WHAT YOU THINK.
I MADE A FRESH ONE FOR YOU.
I DRANK A WHOLE PITCHER UNDER
THE TREE ON THE WAY OVER HERE?
>> NO ALCOHOL OR ALCOHOL?
>> NO ALCOHOL.
SORRY.
CHRISTMAS TIME.
>> REALLY GOOD.
THAT IS DELICIOUS.
>> COOL.
I WILL DRINK IT FOR YOU.
WHAT HAVE WE GOT GOING HERE?
THIS LOOKS AMAZING.
REALLY EXCITED ABOUT THIS.
>> PEACHES WRAPPED IN PAN CHET
THAT GRILLED.
AND THEN FOR THE ENTRAY WE WILL
DO A GRILLED ABOUT PORTABELLA
MUSHROOMS.
>> INDOOR BECAUSE WE HAVE THE
AC, HAVE A GREAT COCKTAIL.
THAT'S GOOD.
GREAT PEACHES WRAPPED IN
PANCETTA.
COMPOSE A SALAD AT THE SAME
TIME.
WHAT DO YOU NEED?
>> IN THE FRIDGE IS A BAG OF
LETTUCE.
>> COOL.
WANT SOME OF THE GREENS IN IT
THERE.
>> I DO.
MAYBE MOST OF IT.
THERE IS ARUGULA ON THE TOP AND
BABY GREENS ON THE BOTTOM.
>> THESE LOOK LIKE RIGHT OUT OF
THE GARDEN GREENS.
THESE LOOK GORGEOUS.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO EAT?
>> SERIOUSLY.
SO, BECKY, MY DEAR, HOW OFTEN
DO YOU EAT YOUR OWN FRUIT?
ANYTHING WITH A PIT, CHERRIES?
PEARS, APRICOTS?
>> MULTIPLE TIMES A DAY.
>> GIVE US OTHER WAYS THAT YOU
COOK WITH THEM AND USE THEM AND
INSPIRE PEOPLE MAKING
VINAIGRETTES OUT OF PEACHES AND
SO ON?
>> PUT THEM IN BASICALLY ALMOST
THE SAME RECIPE MINUS THE DIJON
MUSTARD.
A WHOLE HALF CUT SIDE DOWN
FIRST AND GRILL IT UNTIL THE
CAVITY STARTS TO FILL UP WITH
THE TISSUE AND SERVE IT WARM
WITH VANILLA ICE CREAM AND
SLICE THEM UP AND PUT IT IN
SALAD WITH NUTS AND ALMONDS
ESPECIALLY.
>> LOVE IT.
>> THIS MIGHT BE HOT ENOUGH, DO
YOU THINK.
>> THE PAN WILL TELL YOU IF IT
IS NOT.
IT IS HOT ENOUGH.
>> SOUNDS GLAD CHECK THIS OUT.
LIKE HBASEBALL FIELD WHEN YOU A
GREAT SIZZLE WHEN YOU PUT A
MUSHROOM OR STEAK OR ANYTHING
ON THE GRILL.
IT IS LIKE REALLY GREAT.
>> I THINK I WILL PUT THE
GREENS ON AND THEN I'M GOING TO
WAIT UNTIL WE TURN THESE TO PUT
THE RUMS ON BECAUSE THEY DON'T
TAKE THAT LONG.
>> THEY TAKE JUST A SECOND.
>> AND I CUT THAT BECAUSE THEY
ARE PRETTY DENSE IN THE MIDDLE.
AND THESE ARE NICE BECAUSE THEY
ADD A LITTLE BIT OF BITTERNESS
WITH GOES WELL WITH THE PLUM
FLAVOR.
>> ONE OF THE GREENS THAT CAN
HOLD UP ON THE GRILL OR RAW.
SUPER UNIVERSAL.
>> IT AND THIS TIME OF YEAR
THEY ARE A LITTLE MILDER.
IN THE WINTER TIME THEY ARE A
LITTLE MORE BITTER.
THE YELLOW ONES TEND TO BE MORE
BITTER THAN THE RED ONES ARE.
AND RIDICIA IS REALLY GREAT.
>> PORTABELLAS CAN BE MARINATED
A LONG TIME AND BRAISED COOKED
LOW AND SLOW LIKE IMAGINE A POT
ROAST.
VEGETARIAN STYLE.
>> THE OTHER THING ABOUT
MUSHROOMS IS THEY ARE GOOD FOR
YOU.
HIGH IN PROTEIN WITHOUT THE
FAT.
>> THERE IS A TRICK WHEN YOU
ARE COOKING WITH PROTEIN.
LOT OF PEOPLE WANT TO GET THE
HASH MARKS ON THEIR STEAKS.
SEEING LIKE THIS AND THEN TURN
IT TO SEAR ON THE OTHER SIDE.
IMAGINE ALL THE WATER IS GOING
UP IN THE GLASS AND IF YOU
DON'T TURN THE PROTEIN OVER AND
TRY TO SEER IT ON THE OTHER
SIDE ALL OF THE JUICES ARE
GOING UP TO THE TOP.
IMAGINE THIS IS A STEAK AND YOU
GRILLED THIS WAY.
ALL THE JUICES PUSHING UP, UP,
UP, TURN TO GRILL ON THIS SIDE.
STILL DOING IT IT ON THAT SIDE.
BY THE TIME YOU FLIP IT OVER
YOU ARE ABOUT THREE QUARTERS
COOKED AND DRIED OUT ON ONE
SIDE.
WHEN YOU DO THE GRILL MARKS,
GRILL IT, FLIP IT OVER AND
GRILL ON THE OTHER SIDE AND
THEN GO BACK AND MARK IT ON THE
OTHER AND LOCK IN ALL OF THE
BEAUTIFUL JUICES THAT YOU
BOUGHT THE REALLY EXPENSIVE
PROTEIN OR REALLY EXPENSIVE
PORTABELLO.
YOU.
>> AND PEOPLE PUSH DOWN ON THE
MEAT.
>> LEAVE IT.
>> RIGHT, OTHERWISE YOU PUSH
OUT ALL OF THE JUICES.
IN HERE THE DRIED CUT UP SANTA
ROSA PLUMS.
>> A LITTLE TOASTED MUSTARD
SEED AND PARSLEY.
MUSTARD SEED ADDS CRUNCH.
THIS IS LIKE EATING PROTEIN.
THE HIGHEST NUTRIENTS OF ANY
GRAIN OUT THERE.
LIKE THE MAC DADDY OF THEM ALL.
>> AND HAS REALLY GREAT FLAVOR.
>> TAKE THE BEAUTIFUL
VINAIGRETTE.
YOU SEAT WITH YOUR EYES FIRST
SO PRESENTATION IS KEY HERE.
I LOVE THIS.
WHAT IS GREAT ABOUT THIS DISH,
YOU CAN EAT IT AT ROOM
TEMPERATURE, TOO, RIGHT?
>> MAKE IT AHEAD OF TIME AND DO
IT AT THE LAST MINUTE.
>> I'M A FAN ALREADY.
WHAT A GREAT VEGETARIAN MEAL.
WE HAVE THE GRILLED PEACHES
DONE.
WRAPPED IN PANCHETTA.
AND TOOK THE PLUMS AND THE
SANTA ROSA PLUMS AND THE
GRILLED VERSION RIGHT STRAIGHT
FROM THE FARM AND THEN ALSO THE
DRIED ONES AND MADE A GREAT
SALAD.
A GREAT MUSTARD SEED ADDS A
LITTLE POP AND THE SAME DIJON
VINAIGRETTE IN THE SALAD GREENS
IN HERE AND MUSHROOMS WITH
PLUMS PUREE.
DELICIOUS.
>> COMING UP I'M BAKING IN THE
KIP ONE CHEF BECKY AND THEN WE
SIT DOWN AND ENJOY THIS AMAZING
FOOD.
♪ WE WERE SKIPPING STONES
AND LETTING GO ♪
♪ OVER THE RIVER
AND DOWN THE ROAD ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
AT NATURE VALLEY,
WE KNOW NATURE COMES TOGETHER
IN AMAZING WAYS.
THAT'S WHY WE BRING TOGETHER
NATURAL INGREDIENTS,
LIKE DARK CHOCOLATE
WITH TOASTED OATS,
OR SWEET GOLDEN HONEY.
PERFECT COMBINATIONS OF
NATURE'S DELICIOUS INGREDIENTS,
FROM NATURE VALLEY.
♪
♪ I WAS THINKING
THAT I HOPE THIS NEVER ENDS ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA BARS,
NATURE AT ITS MOST DELICIOUS.
♪
>>> WHAT IS IT LIKE COOKING
WITH A PROFESSIONAL PASTRY
CHEF?
HE I HAVE A PASTRY DEGREE THAT
I HAVEN'T USED IN 12 YEARS?
NOT GOOD.
WE ARE GOING MAKE OUR VERSION
OF KIND OF LIKE AN OPEN FACED
PIISH THING.
>> LIKE A FREEFORM TART WITHOUT
A MOLD.
>> SHE SAID IT AND I'M AGREEING
WITH IT.
MY VERSION OF A PIECRUST WHICH
YOU CAN SEE I ALREADY HAVE AND
THE KICKER, THE TWIST WITH A
SOUR CREAM.
A NICE ACIDY BALANCE TO IT.
BECKY IS TAKING THE PEACHES AND
WE WILL SLICE THEM REALLY THIN.
WHAT I LOVE ABOUT FROG HOLLOW
PEACHES THEY DON'T NEED SUGAR
BECAUSE THEY ARE ARE SO GOOD.
THEY DON'T NEED ANY SUGAR,
GUYS.
SLICE THEM THIN AND THEN WE ADD
A LITTLE BIT OF GINGER AND THAT
IS GOING TO ADD THE NICE LITTLE
ZEST TO IT.
AND ADD A LITTLE LEMMON ZEST IN
THERE TO GIVE IT A SWEET TANG
TO IT.
>> AND WE ARE NOT PEELING THE
PEACHES, RIGHT?
>> NO, WHY WOULD YOU WANT TO
PEEL THEM?
CHECK THIS OUT.
FLOUR AND SALT AND A LITTLE BIT
OF SUGAR.
MIX THESE GUYS TOGETHER.
THE DRY INGREDIENTS FOR THE
CRUST.
MIX THESE TOGETHER AND THIS
STUFF NEEDS TO BE COLD, COLD,
COLD, COLD.
CAN YOU TELL THEM WHY WHILE I
GO AHEAD AND MIX I IT TOGETHER?
SMALL, TOO.
>> IF IT IS TOO SOFT IT WILL
JUST BE STIRRED INTO THE FLOUR
AND NOT KEEP NICE LITTLE LUMPS.
YOU WANT LITTLE PEA SIZED LUMPS
OF BUTTER IN THE DOUGH.
>> WHAT YOU ARE WANTING TO DO
IS LITERALLY PICKING THE BUTTER
UP AND PUSHING IT THROUGH THE
FLOUR AND MASSAGING IT THROUGH.
KIND OF LIKE A BISCUIT METHOD.
>> BUT YOU WANT TO WORK QUICKLY
ALSO.
>> WHICH IS A HINT.
WOULD YOU MIND CRACKING THE EGG
FOR ME IN HERE.
AND GIVE IT WHISK IT IN THERE.
GO AHEAD AND ADD IT IN AND ADD
THE SOUR CREAM.
>> OKAY.
>> THIS IS THE KICKER.
THE SOUR CREAM HAS THE ACID IN
THERE, THE LITTLE TANG THAT
BRINGS IT IT ALL TOGETHER AND I
WILL STAY WITH THE HAND METHOD
HERE.
WHAT I WILL HAVE YOU DO IS GO
AHEAD AND ADD A LITTLE BET OF
GINGER AND A LITTLE BIT OF
LEMON.
DOUGH BRING THIS DOUGH
TOGETHER IT IS BEAUTIFUL AND
DELICIOUS AND FLAKES OF HUGE
PIECES OF BUTTER AND THAT IS
WHAT I'M LOOKING FOR.
YOU CAN'T ROLL IT DOUGH OUT TO
MAKE IT LOOK LIKE THIS.
WRAP IT UP AND REFRIGERATE FOR
AT LEAST TWO HOURS.
WE HAVE OUR DOUGH INTO
NONREFRIGERATED LAND AND ILE
TAKE THE PIECRUST HERE AND TAKE
THE LITTLE BIT OF THAT GINGER
AND DID YOU PUT THE LEMON ZEST
IN THERE, TOO?
>> YOU NEED SUGAR.
>> PUT A LITTLE SUGAR IN HERE.
I THINK YOUR PEACHES ARE GREAT
BUT YOU SAID SUGAR.
>> FLOUR DOWN IN THE BOTTOM OR
ANYTHING TO ABSORB THE PEACH
JUICES.
>> OF COURSE, I WILL PUT FLOUR
AND STUFF TO ABSORB THE PEACH
JUICES.
>> IS THE LINE WHERE YOU ARE
GOING TO HAVE THE EDGES OF THE
FRUIT GO.
>> HE SAID DON'T GO PAST THE
LINE.
I SAID WHAT LINE?
LOOK AT WHAT LINE HE MEAD FOR
ME.
BECKY, DO YOU WANT TO DO THIS
FOR ME.
WE ARE FINISHING UP ADDING THE
LAST OF THE PEACHES HERE AND
BECKY IS GOING FOLD OVER THE
SIDE AND WE WANT TO TAKE A
LITTLE BIT OF EGG WASH.
AND THIS IS KIND OF ONE OF
THOSE PIES THAT DOESN'T HAVE TO
BE BEAUTIFUL ON THE OUTSIDE.
CRUMP IT ANY WAY YOU WANT.
>> VERY FORGIVING.
>> I WILL POP IT IN THE OVEN
AND WE WILL GO OUTSIDE AND HAVE
AN AMAZING DINNER.
WOW, GUYS, THIS LOOKS AMAZING.
FARMER AL THANK YOU FOR THE
GREAT TOUR TODAY AT THE AMAZING
FARM.
CHEF BECKY YOUR AMAZING TREATS
AND GRILLING TECHNIQUES AND IF
YOU WANT THESE RECIPES GO ON
LIVE WELL NETWORK.COM OR LIKE
US ON FACEBOOK OR FOLLOW US ON
TWITTER.
UNTIL THEN, WE ARE GOING TO EAT
AND HAVE A GOOD TIME.
SEE YOU GUYS SOON.
WHERE IS MY PLATE?
MY TIME AT FROG HOLLOW FARM WAS
AMAZING.
NOW, A TRUNK FULL OF PEACHES TO
GO BACK TO THE KITCHEN.
CAN'T SAY, JOE, I DIDN'T GET
YOU ANY FRUIT.
SEE YOU GUYS LATER!
>> NEXT AT 5:00.
NEW DETAILS ABOUT THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT,
INCLUDING A NEW THREAT THAT
FORCED A CHURCH EVACUATION.
>> WE'LL ALSO TAKE YOU THERE
LIVE TO LOOK AT HOW HE SHOOTING
AFFECTED THE COMMUNITY.
>> THE GUN CONTROL DEBATE TAKES
OFF.
WE'LL LOOK AT SENATOR FINE STEIN
OTHERS
You know how much Grandma
wanted to be here
for your fist Christmas?
You see
Grandma lives waaaay down here,
and you live way up here.
Brian, your cousin, he's
a little bit older than you,
he lives here, in Chicago.
And your Aunt Lisa lives here,
in Baltimore.
Uncle Earnie?
Waaay out in Hawaii.
But don't you worry,
we will always be together
for Christmas.
[ Male Announcer ]
Being together
is the best part
of the holidays
and Cheerios is happy
to be part of the family.
You just ate Dallas!
>>> GOOD EVENING AND THANK YOU
FOR JOINING US.
HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE IN NOWN,
CONNECTICUT, ARE AT A MEMORIAL
TONIGHT.
HERE'S A LIVE LOOK.
THEY'RE PAYING RESPECTS TO THOSE
WHO LOST THEIR LIVES IN THE
SCHOOL TRAGEDY.
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS AT THE
MEMORIAL AND WILL BE SPEAKIN