AND WHILE MEL IS COMING BACK,
THIS IS A CLIP FROM HIS NEW
BOXED SET.
>> TRUTH IS, I DON'T KNOW IF HE
DESERVES IT, DO YOU?
A LOT OF PEOPLE DON'T AGREE WITH
THIS.
I'D LIKE TO CUT, RIGHT NOW, CUT
OUTSIDE AND SEE THE
DEMONSTRATION AGAINST IT.
ROLL THE TAPE.
FOR 25 YEARS, HE MADE ME OUT TO
BE THIS JEWISH PERSON.
I'M GOING TO REVEAL, AM I REALLY
A GENTILE WORN IN WACO, TEXAS.
THIS IS NOT MY NOSE, LOOK, LOOK
CAREFULLY.
WATCH, WATCH ME.
THIS IS MOTT, THIS IS NOT --
THIS IS NOT -- 25 YEARS, I'M
WEARING THIS NOSE.
>> Jimmy: THAT'S MEL BROOKS
HONORING HIS FRIEND CARL REINER.
THAT IS FANTASTIC.
>> CARL NEVER, NEVER EXPECTED ME
TO DO ANYTHING THAT CRAZY.
>> Jimmy: IT'S KIND OF A WEIRD
THING WHERE YOU CAN GO OUT WITH
A PROSTHETIC NOSE AND PEOPLE
DON'T NOTICE IT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> IT'S TRUE.
WHEN YOU'RE REALLY JEWISH, IT
DOESN'T MAKE A BIT OF
DIFFERENCE.
BUT CARL, I SEE CARL, I'LL SEE
HIM LATER TONIGHT, WE'LL BE
WATCHING THIS LATER TONIGHT.
I SEE HIM ALMOST EVERY NIGHT.
I LOVE THAT GUY.
>> Jimmy: I LOVE THE IDEA OF YOU
GUYS HANGING OUT TOGETHER.
>> I SAID TO CARL THE OTHER
NIGHT, THIS IS REALLY FUNNY, I
SAID, CARL, YOU KNOW, YOU'RE 90,
GOING TO BE 91, YOU'RE AMAZING.
JUST, I'M -- I'M JUST SO AMAZED
AT EVERYTHING YOU DO.
CAN I ASK A PERSONAL QUESTION?
HE SAID, OF COURSE.
EVERY ONCE IN AWHILE, DO YOU
EVER ACHIEVE AN ERECTION?
THIS IS ALL TRUE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
AND HE -- AND CARL SAID, I DO, I
DO, NOT SO NOTICE IT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
THAT'S -- TRUE LIFE --
>> Jimmy: INSURRECTION, I THINK,
ACTUALLY.
WOW, THAT'S -- AND HOW OFTEN ARE
YOU GUYS TOGETHER DURING THE
WEEK?
>> COUPLE OF NIGHTS A WEEK.
>> Jimmy: THAT'S GREAT.
I LOVE THE IDEA OF YOU GUYS
HANGING OUT.
>> WE HAVE CHICKEN.
>> Jimmy: OH, YOU DO?
IS IT DELIVERED OR DO YOU PICK
IT UP ON THE WAY OVER?
>> NO, I PICK IT UP ON THE WAY
OVER.
YOU KNOW, CHICKEN, COLESLAW AND
A TANGERINE.
THAT'S ABOUT IT.
>> Jimmy: YOU'VE DONE SO MANY
TELEVISION APPEARANCES AND THERE
ARE SO MANY GREAT TELEVISION
APPEARANCES, COBBLED TOGETHER
FOR THIS DVD.
HAVE YOU EVER BEEN TRULY
EMBARRASSED ON TELEVISION?
>> ONLY ONCE.
>> Jimmy: WHEN WAS THAT?
>> I'M NEVER REALLY EMBARRASSED
BUT I WAS.
YOU KNOW, I DID A SHOW WHEN I
WAS -- 20 YEARS AGO, 30 YEARS
AGO AND IT WAS CALLED "I GUESS."
AND THE HOST WAS A WONDERFUL GUY
WITH BLACK HORN RIMMED GLASSES
AND A CREW CUT AND THE OLDER
PEOPLE HERE MIGHT REMEMBER HIM.
HE WAS KIND OF, THE BEST HOST
EVER, HIS NAME WAS BILL CULLEN.
>> Jimmy: OH, BILL CULLEN, OKAY,
YEAH.
>> HE WAS REALLY GREAT.
AND HE ALWAYS DID -- HE WAS
ALWAYS BEHIND THIS LITTLE DESK
AND HE WAS ALWAYS EASY AND QUICK
AND FAST AND WONDERFUL AND AT
THE END OF THE SHOW, I DID -- I
WAS -- I DID A SHOW CALLED "I
GUESS."
"EYE GUESS."
>> TWO Us?
>> WELL, I SPELL IT WITH TWO Us.
SO, AT THE END OF THE SHOW, HE
SAID, MEL, MEL, YOU WERE SO
FUNNY, YOU WERE SO WONDERFUL, I
CAN'T THANK YOU FOR COMING ON
THE SHOW AND BEING HERE AND
BEING HERE IN PERSON, I SAID,
OH, PLEASE, BILL.
AND LISTEN.
HE GETS UP FROM BEHIND THE DESK,
THIS IS ALL TRUE.
HE GETS UP FROM BEHIND THE DESK
AND HE KIND OF STARTS TOWARDS ME
TO GIVE ME A HUG AND HE'S, YOU
KNOW, SO, I'M -- I SAY, WELL,
OKAY.
WE'RE DOING JERRY LEWIS.
ALL RIGHT.
SO, WE'RE DOING JERRY LEWIS.
I DON'T WANT TO HURT HIS
FEELINGS.
I'LL DO JERRY LEWIS.
I'M LIKE, OH, BILL.
AND JULIA, MY PARTNER -- MY
PARTNER, JULIA IS SCREAMING FROM
BEHIND, HE'S HAD POLIO, HE'S
CRIPPLED!
HE'S HAD POLIO.
AND I'M WALKING AND I'M -- I
SAY -- TOO LATE!
AND --
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Jimmy: TOO LATE.
TOO LATE.
WELL -- THERE YOU GO.
THAT IS THE BOXED SET.
"THE INCREDIBLE MEL BROOKS."
THE INCREDIBLE MEL BROOKS,
EVERYBODY.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH JAKE
TAPPER.
,,
GO OLIVE GARDEN'S 2 FOR $25.
AN ITALIAN DINNER FOR 2.
START WITH ALL THE FRESH SALAD
AND WARM BREADSTICKS YOU WANT.
CHOOSE AN APPETIZER
MADE FOR SHARING.
THEN TWO DELICIOUS ENTREES
FROM FIVE OF OUR FAVORITES.
CLASSICS LIKE
EGGPLANT PARMAGIANA.
OR NEW FAVORITES LIKE
SMOKED MOZZARELLA CHICKEN.
THREE COURSES,
TWO PEOPLE, JUST $25
BUT ONLY FOR A LIMITED TIME.
GO OLIVE GARDEN.
AND TRY OUR UNLIMITED
HOMEMADE SOUP, CRISP SALAD,
AND WARM BREADSTICKS
LUNCH, JUST $6.95.
This season, give Craftsman
tools and give the gifts that
keep on giving.
CRAFTSMAN. GUYS'
FAVORITES GUARANTEED.
FIND IT AT SEARS.
[ Female Announcer ]
CHARMIN ULTRA SOFT IS SO SOFT
YOU'LL HAVE TO REMIND
YOUR FAMILY THEY CAN USE LESS.
IT'S MADE WITH EXTRA CUSHIONS
THAT ARE SOFT
AND MORE ABSORBENT.
PLUS YOU CAN USE
FOUR TIMES LESS.
CHARMIN ULTRA SOFT.
Want to start the day
with something heart healthy
and delicious?
You're a talking bee...
Honey Nut Cheerios
has whole grain oats
that can help
lower cholesterol.
and it tastes good?
Sure does!
Right...
♪
Wow.
Delicious, right?
Yeah.
It's the honey,
it makes it taste so...
♪
Well, would you
look at the time...
What's the rush?
Be happy. Be healthy.
Here's a better idea.
Pillsbury Grands!
Flaky Layers Biscuits
In just 15 minutes
the light delicate layers
add a layer of warmth
to your next dinner.
Pillsbury Grands Biscuits
Let the making begin.
FASTER THAN MANDY CAN HANG UP
ON MR. MONDAY.
YOU HANG UP FIRST.
[ Female Announcer ]
IN JUST 60 SECONDS, YOU'VE GOT
SNACK-DEFYING, SATISFYING
TOTINO'S PIZZA ROLLS.
[ ringing ]
IT'S ON. LET'S ROLL.
>> Dicky: NEXT WEEK ON "JIMMY
KIMMEL LIVE," HUGH JACKMAN,
SAMUEL L. JACKSON, FROM "THE
OFFICE" JENNA FISCHER.
AND THE CAST OF "JERSEY SHORE."
PLUS, MUSIC FROM TWO CHAINS AND
ED SHARON.
THE "JIMMY KIMMEL LIVE" CONCERT
SERIES SPONSORED BY BUD LIGHT.
TO STREAM OFF-AIR PERFORMANCES
AND OTHER MUSIC PERFORMANCES, GO
TO JIMMYKIMMELLIVE.COM.
SEARCH JIMMY KIM NEL THE ITUNES
APP STORE TO GET IT NOW.
SADLY, THEIR BROTHER'S
WHITE CHRISTMAS
JUST GOT "BLACKED OUT."
[ Brother ]
BUT IT'S THE FAMILY PARTY!
REALLY JINGLES YOUR BELLS,
DOESN'T IT?
MY GIFT TO YOU!
THE Capital One Venture Card!
FOR ANY FLIGHT, ANY TIME!
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE!
HOW ILLUMINATING.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
LET ME GUESS, AM I
ON THE NAUGHTY LIST AGAIN?
HO HO HO!
CRAFTED WITH A TOUCH
OF WHISKY, WINE, AND BEER
BY HIGHLY SKILLED CHEFS.
YEP, THIS IS REAL.
DOUBLE BARREL WHISKY SIRLOINS
AND NEW NAPA CHICKEN
& PORTOBELLOS,
STARTING AT $9.99.
SEE YOU TOMORROW.
IT'S NOT FOR COLDS,
IT'S NOT FOR PAIN,
IT'S JUST FOR SLEEP.
BECAUSE SLEEP
IS A BEAUTIFUL THING.
♪
ZZZQUIL,
THE NON-HABIT FORMING SLEEP-AID
FROM THE MAKERS OF NYQUIL.
McDonald's TENDER,
JUICY Chicken McNuggets
IN SPICY BUFFALO
AND CREAMY RANCH SAUCE.
JUST $4.99 FOR 20 OF YOUR
FAVORITE Chicken McNuggets.
MORE WAYS TO LOVE McNuggets.
♪
[Spider-Man]
WE GOT THIS.
♪
[Mom]
THIS HERO STUFF IS EASY!
In♪  ducing
Grey Goose Cherry Noir
♪
>> Jimmy: STILL TO COME, MUSIC
FROM JASON ALDEAN.
THE GUY HAD POLIO.
[ LAUGHTER ]
FOR THE LAST FOUR YEARS, OUR
NEXT GUEST HAS SERVED AS ABC
NEWS SENIOR WHITE HOUSE
CORRESPONDENT, WHICH MEANS HE'S
DEFINITELY SEEN PRESIDENT OBAMA
IN HIS UNDERPANTS.
HE'S WRITTEN THIS NEW BOOK, IT'S
CALLED "THE OUTPOST: AN UNTOLD
STORY OF AMERICAN VALOR."
PLEASE WELCOME JAKE TAPPER.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Jimmy: HOW ARE YOU?
>> HOW ABOUT THAT MEL BROOKS?
>> Jimmy: GOOD LUCK FOLLOWING
THAT.
>> I KNOW.
I'M JUST GOING TO GET UP RIGHT
NOW.
>> Jimmy: REALLY.
THERE'S ALMOST NO POINT IN
CONTINUING.
>> I'M NOT GOING TO TRY TO MAKE
A JOKE AFTER THAT.
CAN YOU IMAGINE HIM AND REINER
TONIGHT WATCHING THAT?
THAT KIMMEL, HE'S GOING PLACES.
>> Jimmy: I LIKE TO IMAGINE
THAT.
I LIKE, IN FACT, I'M GOING TO
FOLLOW HIM HOME AND GO TO IT
WITH THEM, WATCH IT WITH THEM.
NOW, JAKE, YOU'VE WRITTEN THIS
BOOK AND THIS IS REALLY AN
EXCELLENT BOOK AND I THINK -- I
THINK A LOT OF PEOPLE DON'T
KNOW, DON'T HAVE ANY IDEA WHAT
GOES ON IN AFGHANISTAN.
I, FOR ONE, DID NOT HAVE ANY
IDEA WHAT WAS GOING ON IN
AFGHANISTAN UNTIL I READ THIS.
AND THE INTERVIEWS THAT YOU --
DID YOU GO OVER THERE?
>> A COUPLE OF TIMES.
>> Jimmy: YOU INTERVIEWED
HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE, INCLUDING OF
PEOPLE WHO AREN'T NECESSARILY ON
OUR SIDE.
>> RIGHT.
I DID INTERVIEW AN INSURGENT OR
TWO.
>> Jimmy: AND HOW DO YOU
INTERVIEW AN INSURGENT?
ARE THEY INCREDULOUS OVER THERE?
WHAT DO YOU GET?
>> I HAD A FIXER AND THE FIXER
WAS FROM THIS REMOTE REGION,
WHERE THE MAN WHO WOULD BE KING
TOOK PLACE, THE OLD NOVELLA AND
THE MOVIE WITH MICHAEL CAINE.
AND THIS FIXER FOUND AN
INSURGENT AND IT WAS SO BIZARRE.
I'M SITTING IN MY NICE LITTLE
STUDY WITH MY COMPUTER ON, MY
MAC AND I'M SKYPING WITH AN
INSURGENT.
>> Jimmy: UNBELIEVABLE.
>> AND THE FIXER IS TRANSLATING
AND IDENTIFIED AS FAROOK IN THE
BOOK.
NOT HIS REAL NAME.
AND HE IS -- HE'S ONE OF THE
MANY GUYS WHO HAS COME AND
RECONCILED WITH THE GOVERNMENT,
SO, HE'S NO LONGER AN INSURGENT.
>> Jimmy: OKAY.
>> SO, IT'S LIKE I KNOW WHERE
THE BAD GUY IS.
HE'S ACTUALLY COOL NOW.
>> Jimmy: IN THE BOOK, YOU TALK
ABOUT HOW THEY'RE KIND OF A
DIFFERENT CULTURE FROM THE OTHER
AFGHANS.
>> IT'S LIKE THE AFGHANISTAN OF
AFGHANISTAN.
THEY ARE COMPLETELY CUT OFF.
THEY DON'T WANT ANYBODY THERE.
AND THEY WERE THE LAST ONES TO
CONVERT TO ISLAM.
AND THE FIRST ONES TO TAKE UP
ARMS AGAINST THE SOVIETS.
THEY ARE A REBELLIOUS PEOPLE.
>> Jimmy: THEY WILL SAY PRETTY
MUCH ANYTHING THEY NEED TO SAY
TO WHOMEVER WANDERS INTO THEIR
AREA JUST TO GET THEM TO GO
AWAY.
>> THEY THOUGHT WHEN A LOT OF
THE AMERICANS CAME IN, THEY
THOUGHT THEY WERE RUSSIANS.
THEY THOUGHT THEY WERE RUSSIANS
AND IN FACT, THIS OUTPOST THAT I
PROFILE, OUTSIDE IT ARE THE
HOLLOWED OUT SHELLS OF FORMER
SOVIET PERSONNEL CARRIERS,
WHICH, FOR A LOT OF THE
SOLDIERS, WAS NOT REASSURING.
>> Jimmy: SO, THEY'RE NOT
WATCHING CABLE NEWS.
THEY ARE NOT GETTING CNN AND AL
JAZEERA IN THOSE PLACES --
>> A LOT OF SHORT WAVE RADIO.
IT DEPENDS ON THE TOWN, BUT
YEAH, NO, IT'S CUT OFF FROM A
LOT OF CIVILIZATION.
>> Jimmy: HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN
COVERING THE WHITE HOUSE FOR
ABC?
>> SINCE PRESIDENT OBAMA WAS
ELECTED.
>> Jimmy: YOU WERE ON THE
CAMPAIGN TRAIL THIS TIME AROUND.
>> WEIRD BEING IN A NONSWING
STATE.
I FEEL LIKE I SHOULD BE IN
WISCONSIN OR OHIO.
>> Jimmy: THERE'S NO SWINGING
HERE.
>> ALL THESE -- IT'S --
EVERYBODY IS A DEMOCRAT HERE.
I'M USED TO GOING TO STATES
WHERE IT IS COMPLETELY DIVIDED
DOWN THE MIDDLE.
>> Jimmy: YOU WENT TO EVERY TOWN
THAT OBAMA WENT TO.
>> YEAH, MADISON, DES MOINES.
>> Jimmy: WHAT IS THAT LIKE?
YOU MUST BE LIKE THE GREATEST
PACKER IN THE WORLD.
>> I'M THE WORST.
I WAS LIKE BEYONCE.
I HAD LIKE THESE TWO HUGE BAGS.
IT WAS EMBARRASSING.
I HAD TO WEAR A LOT OF SUITS AND
YOU HAVE TO, YOU KNOW, FLORIDA,
SWING STATE, VERY DIFFERENT
WEATHER THAN, YOU KNOW,
WISCONSIN, SWING STATE.
>> Jimmy: OKAY.
>> SO, I HAD A LOT OF STUFF TO
BRING.
>> Jimmy: DO YOU NOT KNOW HOW
LONG YOU'RE GOING TO BE GONE?
>> NO.
YOU PACK FOR LIKE THREE WEEKS.
>> Jimmy: AND YOU GO AND YOU
FOLLOW THE PRESIDENT.
>> YEAH.
>> Jimmy: YOU GET TO KNOW HIM IN
THIS SITUATION?
>> I GOT TO KNOW HIM A LOT
BETTER IN 2008 WHEN I WAS ON THE
SAME PLANE WITH HIM.
THIS TIME, WE HAVE A PRESS
CHARTER.
SOMETIMES YOU ROTATE INTO AIR
FORCE ONE.
MOST OF THE TIME NOT.
HE KNOWS ME BY NOW.
>> Jimmy: I GOT YOU.
YOU BUST THEIR BALLS CONSTANTLY
IN THOSE PRESS CONFERENCES.
DO THEY LIKE YOU, DO YOU THINK?
LIKE, JAY CARNEY AND THESE GUYS
THAT YOU ASK THESE QUESTIONS, DO
THEY LIKE YOU?
>> IT'S LIKE THE OLD, "IT'S
BETTER TO BE RESPECTED THAN
LIKED."
>> Jimmy: SO NO, THEY DON'T LIKE
YOU.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> I'M NOT TRYING TO BE LIKE
THAT.
I'M TRYING TO BE A PAIN IN THEIR
BUTT.
THAT'S THE JOB.
DOESN'T MATTER WHO IS IN THE
SEAT, WHETHER OR NOT YOU THINK
OH, HE'S COOL, HE'S THE
PRESIDENT, I'M SUPPOSED TO HOLD
HIM ACCOUNTABLE.
>> Jimmy: THAT WOULD BE THE
HARDEST THING TO ME.
ESPECIALLY IF YOU GET TO LIKE
SOMEBODY OR WHATEVER AND YOU ARE
REALLY DEALING WITH THEM EVERY
SINGLE DAY AND TO ASK THE
QUESTIONS, I WATCH YOU SOMETIMES
AND I CAN'T BELIEVE THIS IS A
PERSON I KNOW BECAUSE YOU
REALLY, REALLY ARE A BALL BUSTER
IN EVERY SENSE OF THE WORD.
>> THANK YOU.
[ LAUGHTER ]
THAT'S MY JOB.
THAT'S WHAT I'M PAID TO YOU.
>> Jimmy: WERE YOU A DIFFICULT
CHILD?
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> YES, BUT THAT'S IRRELEVANT.
>> Jimmy: NOTHING TO DO WITH
THAT?
IN CLASS, DID THE TEACHERS GO,
OH, GOD, HERE'S TAPPER AGAIN.
>> YEAH.
COME TO THINK OF IT, PROBABLY
SOME ENGLISH TEACHERS GOING, I
KNEW HE WAS GOING TO PUT THOSE
POWERS TO EVIL.
>> Jimmy: IT TURNS OUT NOT TO
EVIL.
NOW, YOU, DO YOU JOKE AROUND
WITH THE PRESIDENT, DO YOU --
>> ON OCCASION.
ON OCCASION.
NOT A LOT.
BUT YOU KNOW, I COVERED HIM FOR
SO LONG THAT IT'S TOUGH.
YOU KNOW, YOU LET YOUR GUARD
DOWN.
ONE TIME, HE RECENTLY, WE ALL
HAVE OUR IMITATIONS, OUR
IMPRESSIONS OF THE PRESIDENT.
AND WE DO THEM WHEN HE'S NOT
AROUND -- AH, LOOK.
YOU DO THEM AND --
>> Jimmy: THEY ALL START WITH
LOOK.
>> AND -- WELL, THAT'S ONE OF
THEM.
ANYWAY, HE CAME INTO THE PRESS
ROOM IN AUGUST AND I WAS KIND OF
THROWN AND I JUST -- I FORGOT
WHERE I WAS AND EVERYBODY WAS
TELEVISING IT AND I -- HELLO,
EVERYBODY.
AND HE LOOKED AT ME, LIKE,
BECAUSE I DID THIS OBAMA
IMPRESSION THAT EVERYBODY WAS
USED TO ME DOING AND HE LOOKED
AT ME -- THAT'S PRETTY GOOD.
>> Jimmy: BUSTED.
>> YEAH.
I'M LIKE, THANKS, I'VE BEEN
WORKING ON IT FOR A LONG TIME.
>> Jimmy: CAN THEY THROW YOU OFF
THE DETAIL?
CAN THEY CALL ABC, SAY, JAKE'S
NOT ALLOWED IN THE WHITE HOUSE
ANYMORE.
>> FOR BAD IMPRESSIONS?
>> Jimmy: FOR ANYTHING.
>> NO, I MEAN, I GUESS THEY
COULD.
I MEAN, BUT NOT WHEN YOU'RE WITH
ABC NEWS.
>> Jimmy: RIGHT.
IT WOULDN'T BE APPROPRIATE.
>> PRETTY GOOD SENSE OF HUMOR.
WHAT PEOPLE MAY NOT KNOW IS THAT
JIMMY IS A FAILED CARTOONIST, AS
I AM.
WE BOTH PURSUED THAT AT ONE
POINT.
>> Jimmy: YOU ARE A VERY GOOD
ARTIST, ACTUALLY.
>> YOU ARE --
>> Jimmy: LET'S NOT GET INTO
EACH OTHER HERE.
>> YOU SHOULD KNOW, HE GAVE ME
SOME PENS AND SO A COUPLE OF THE
MAPS IN HERE WERE DRAWN WITH
YOUR PENS.
>> Jimmy: I FEEL LIKE I'VE
WRITTEN SOMETHING.
>> I SHOULD HAVE ACKNOWLEDGED.
JIM THIS IS THE BOOK.
IT IS WELL WORTH READING.
JAKE TAPPER, EVERYBODY.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH JASON
DICK THE "JIMMY KIMMEL LIVE"
CONCERT SERIES SPONSORED BY BUD
LIGHT.
>> Jimmy: THIS IS HIS NEW CD.
"NIGHT TRAIN."
HERE WITH THE SONG "TAKE A
LITTLE RIDE," JASON ALDEAN!
♪
♪ BEEN GOIN' 'ROUND AND 'ROUND
ALL DAY BALIN' SOME HAY AND
STACKIN' IT ALL UP ♪
♪ CAN'T WAIT FOR THE SUN TO GO
DOWN ROLL INTO TOWN SHINE THE
OLD TRUCK UP ♪
♪ SWING BY THE QUICK STOP GRAB A
COUPLE ROCKY TOPS THEN EASE ON
OUT YOUR WAY TO YOUR PLACE ♪
♪ AROUND 8:00 I'M JUST READY TO
RIDE THIS CHEVY RIDE THIS CHEVY
DOWN ♪
♪ A LITTLE BACK ROAD SLIDE YOUR
PRETTY LITTLE SELF ON OVER GET A
LITTLE CLOSER ♪
♪ TURN UP THE RADIO PUT YOUR
PRETTY PINK TOES ON THE DASH
LEAN THE SEAT BACK ♪
♪ MAN I SWEAR THERE AIN'T
NOTHIN' LOOKS BETTER THAN THAT
SWEET TAN ♪  LITTLE THING WITH
NOTHIN' TO DO I WANNA TAKE A
LITTLE RIDE WITH YOU ♪
♪ I HOPE YOU'RE WEARIN' THOSE
FRAYED OUT CUTOFFS MAKES ME
WANNA GET LOST OUT IN THE
MOONLIGHT ♪
♪ DROP THE TAILGATE DOWN ON A
TURN-ROW WATCH THE CORN GROW
BABY THAT'S A GOOD NIGHT ♪
♪ ANYONE FROM THE HEARTLAND IS
GONNA UNDERSTAND WHAT I'M
TALKIN' ABOUT RIGHT NOW ♪
♪ AIN'T NO DOUBT WE GOT A GAME
PLAN I'M JUST READY TO RIDE THIS
CHEVY ♪
♪ RIDE THIS CHEVY DOWN A LITTLE
BACK ROAD SLIDE YOUR PRETTY
LITTLE SELF ON OVER ♪  GET A
LITTLE CLOSER TURN UP THE RADIO
PUT YOUR PRETTY PINK TOES ON THE
DASH ♪
♪ LEAN THE SEAT BACK MAN I SWEAR
THERE AIN'T NOTHIN' LOOKS
BETTER ♪
♪ THAN THAT SWEET TAN LITTLE
THING WITH NOTHIN' TO DO I WANNA
TAKE A ♪  LITTLE RIDE WITH
YOU ♪
♪ I'M JUST READY TO RIDE THIS
CHEVY RIDE THIS CHEVY DOWN ♪
♪ A LITTLE BACK ROAD SLIDE YOUR
PRETTY LITTLE SELF ON OVER GET A
LITTLE CLOSER ♪
♪ YOU CAN PLAY MY RADIO PUT YOUR
PRETTY PINK TOES ON THE DASH
LEAN THE SEAT BACK ♪
♪ MAN I SWEAR THERE AIN'T
NOTHIN' LOOKS BETTER THAN THAT
SWEET TAN LITTLE THING ♪
♪ WITH NOTHIN' TO DO I WANNA
TAKE A LITTLE RIDE WITH YOU I
WANNA TAKE A ♪  LITTLE RIDE
WITH YOU I WANNA TAKE A LITTLE
RIDE WITH YOU ♪
♪
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Jimmy: THIS IS JASON ALDEAN'S
NEW CD.
IT'S CALLED "NIGHT TRAIN," IT IS
OUT NOW.
SEE A BONUS SONG AT
JIMMYKIMMELLIVE.COM.
THANKS TO MEL BROOKS, THANKS TO
JAKE TAPPER, THANKS TO FRED
WILLARD.
APOLOGIES TO MATT DAMON, WE DID
RUN OUT OF TIME FOR HIM.
GOOD NIGHT!
>> Terry: INDIVIDUAL I 0 THE
PHONE IS CONTINUING TO HEAR WHAT
YOU BELIEVE TO BE ....
>> ATTACK ON AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
>> EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY
TODAY.
>> MOST OF THE BULLETS AIMED AT
LITTLE CHILDREN.
>> WE HEARD THIS RACKET.
>> AND THEN CHAOS AND CONFUSION
AS YOUNG SURVIVORS WERE LED OUT
OF THE SCHOOL.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE THAT
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN,
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF FIVE AND TEN YEARS
OLD.
>> Dan: GOOD EVENING.
I'M DAN ASHLEY.
>> Ama: I'M AMA DAETZ.
A LOSS UNIMAGINABLE SCALE.
>> A MAN STARTED SHOOTING WITH
CHILLING AGO.
>> WAS THERE ARE 27 VICTIMS, 20
OF THEM CHILDREN AND 7 ADULTS.
WE HAVE TEAM COVERAGE BEGINNING
IN CONNECTICUT.
>> EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY
TODAY.
>> Reporter: A QUAINT NEW
ENGLAND SUBURB.
>> I'M TERRIFIED.
>> BECAME A SCENE OF HORROR.
A GUNMAN IDENTIFIED AS ADAM
LANZA BARGED INTO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND BEGIN
SHOOTING.
>> COMPLETE CHAOS.
>> TEACHERS RUSHED TO SHEPPARD
THE YUCK CHILDREN TO SAFETY.
THEY WERE TOLD TO CLOSE THEIR
EYES ON THE WAY OUT.
>> WE ALL PUT OUR HANDS ON OTHER
PEOPLE'S SHOURDZ AND TEACHER LED
THE FIRST PERSON'S HAND AND LEAD
US OUT.
>> ONE SPOKE EXCLUSIVELY TO
DIANE SAWYER.
>> I NEED TO KNOW I LOVE YOU ALL
VERY MUCH.
IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY BECAUSE
THAT WAS THE LAST THING I WOULD
HAVE HEAR.
>> ALL EINTS THE INDIVIDUAL I
HAVE ON THE PHONE CONTINUES TO
BELIEVE WHAT HE HEARS IS
GUNFIRE.
>> A SMALL ARM SWARMED THE
SCHOOL BUT NOT BEFORE THE GUNMAN
TOOK HIS TOLL.
>> ALL AFTERNOON DESPERATE
PARENTS CONVERGED.
SOME TOOK THEIR CHILDREN AWAY
AND OTHERS WENT AWAY WITH
UNIMAGINABLE GRIEF THE VICTIMS
WERE REMEMBERED AT A CANDLELIGHT
VIGIL IN NEWTOWN.
SIMILAR PRAYER SERVICES ARE
GOING ON ALL OVER THE COUNTRY
WITH PEOPLE PAYING THEIR
RESPECTS TO THE FALLEN WHAT IS A
TRUE NATIONAL TRAGEDY.
>> Dan: TONIGHT WE ARE LEARNING
MORE ABOUT HIM.
HE WAS AN HONOR STUDENT IN HIGH
SCHOOL.
HE DID NOT APPEAR IN HIS HIGH
SCHOOL YEAR BOOK.
HIS PARENTS DIVORCED.
HIS FATHER IS VICE PRESIDENT OF
GEY CAPITAL AND REMARRIED.
BOTH HAD LEGALLY WEAPONS.
>> LANZA TOLD OFFICERS HE HAD
NOT SEEN HIS BROTHER IN YEARS
AND NOT BEEN IN CLOSE CONTACT
WITH HIM.
POLICE STRESS THAT HE IS NOT A
SWHEENGD COOPERATING FULLY WITH
THE INVESTIGATION.
>> HUNDREDS PACKED THE CATHOLIC