>> THE ANSWER TO THAT QUESTION
WAS "SNAP OUT OF IT."
AND WELCOME BACK TO THE LAST DAY
OF MILLIONAIRE'S BROADWAY
GIVEAWAY WEEK.
WE'RE HERE WITH DANA GOLD
FROM NEW YORK,
OUR ATTORNEY, WHO'S GOT
$24,500 IN THE BANK.
OUT OF LIFELINES RIGHT NOW.
JUST 7 AWAY FROM THE MILLION,
3 LE
YOU GET THESE 3 RIGHT,
AND YOU WILL KEEP ALL THE MONEY
IN YOUR BANK.
AND THIS NEXT QUESTION
IS OUR BROADWAY QUESTION,
SO THE AUDIENCE IS REALLY
EXCITED ABOUT THAT ONE.
[cheers and applause]
ALL RIGHT, DANA, KID,
ARE YOU READY?
>> I'M READY.
>> THEN LET'S PLAY.
[dramatic musical flourish]
HERE YOU GO, DANA.
WHAT POPULAR BROADWAY MUSICAL
ADVERTISES ITSELF
AS THE "SUPERCALEXTRAVAGANZA"?
>> I KNOW THAT IS "C,"
MARY POPPINS, FINAL ANSWER.
[cheers and applause]
>> YOU GOT IT.
IT IS MARY POPPINS.
ALL RIGHT, DANA,
LET'S SEE THE MONEY.
FIRST OF ALL, WE'RE GONNA PUT
HOW MUCH MORE IN YOUR BANK?
WE'LL ADD ANOTHER $3,000
IN YOUR BANK,
UP TO $27,500.
YOU NOW HAVE TICKETS TO NEWSIES.
[audience shouting]
YOU'RE ANIMALS!
SELECT A NUMBER FROM 1 TO 13
TO SEE WHICH AUDIENCE ROW
WINS TICKETS TO THE NEWSIES.
>> 4.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU'RE GOING TO NEWSIES, GUYS.
CONGRATULATIONS.
AND IT IS THE TONY WINNER.
IT'S A GREAT MUSICAL.
ALL RIGHT, THESE GUYS
ARE VERY HAPPY.
YOU'RE VERY HAPPY, OBVIOUSLY.
>> YEAH.
>> THERE'S 2 QUESTIONS LEFT
IN ROUND 1.
"TALL STATUES" IS THE CATEGORY.
NAMED ONE OF THE NEW
"SEVEN WONDERS OF THE WORLD,"
A 125-FOOT-TALL STATUE OF JESUS
IN RIO DE JANEIRO
IS NAMED "CHRIST THE" WHAT?
>> GIANT SEEMS TOO OBVIOUS.
I...
HOW MUCH DO I HAVE
IN THE BANK NOW?
>> YOU HAVE $27,500.
YOU COULD WALK WITH $13,750.
>> YOU KNOW, MEREDITH, THAT'S--
I COULD DO A LOT WITH $13,000.
I DON'T KNOW.
I HAVE NO MORE LIFELINES.
SO I'M GONNA WALK.
>> IS THAT A FINAL?
>> YES, THAT'S FINAL.
[cheers and applause]
>> THE ANSWER WAS "B,"
REDEEMER.
BUT YOU'RE WALKING WITH $13,750
AND TICKETS TO NEWSIES,
WHICH IS FANTASTIC.
I'M GONNA GIVE YOU A BIG HUG.
YOU GO SAY HI TO YOUR FOLKS
OVER THERE.
THEY'D LIKE A HUG.
I'LL TELL THE AUDIENCE AT HOME
THAT IS IT FOR THIS WEEK
OF MILLIONAIRE.
THANKS SO MUCH FOR JOINING US.
WE'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME.
[ Man ] WHEN YOU WANT TO GIVE
YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM SOME SUPPORT
TRY AIRBORNE!
WITH ZINC, ECHINACEA, GINGER
AND A BLAST OF VITAMIN C.
AIRBORNE. REAL IMMUNE SUPPORT.
>> CLOSED CAPTIONING
SPONSORED BY:
WHAT IS SUBWAY?
UH, LUNCH FOR $400.
AND THAT WOULD BE CARP.
BETH, GO AGAIN.
UH, TIME FOR LUNCH
FOR $600.
WHAT'S A CANNOLI?
LEAVE THE CANNOLIS.
I MEAN, TAKE THE--LEAVE THE GUN,
TAKE THE CANNOLI, RIGHT.
INDEED.
UH, LUNCH FOR $800, PLEASE.
WHAT IS TURTLE?
UH, LUNCH FOR $1,000.
WHAT IS AMBROSIA?
$1,000 MORE
COMING YOUR WAY.
JOHN, PAUL, AND GEORGE
FOR $400.
WHO IS PAUL REVERE?
UH, JOHN, PAUL, GEORGE
FOR $1,000.
AND THAT WAS
THE BRITISH ACTOR
PAUL SCOFIELD. JASON.
JOHN, PAUL, GEORGE
FOR $800.
WHO IS DULLES?
JOHN FOSTER DULLES.
JOHN, PAUL, GEORGE
FOR $600.
WELL, YOU WERE LOOKING FOR IT,
AND YOU FOUND IT.
AND YOU HAVE
$2,000 MORE THAN LESLIE.
I'LL WAGER $1,000, PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT,YOU HAVE
HERE IS THE CLUE.LESLIE.
HE'S THE BOTANIST
SEEN HERE IN 1940.
WHO IS
GEORGE WASHINGTON CARVER?
S THE ONE.
THAT'S WHERE
OUR GEORGE COMES IN.
THREE CLUES LEFT.
WE HAVE TO GO BACK TO CANADA.
I KNOW YOU GUYS
ARE NOT EAGER TO DO THAT.
I LIKE CANADA,
JUST'HE SINGERS SO MUCH.
UH, CANADA ROCKS FOR $600.
WHAT'S THE "SAFETY DANCE"?
YES. UH, $800.
WHAT'S ARCADE FIRE?
AND NOW
THE LAST ONE...
WHAT IS RUSH?
AND THAT
TAKES YOU TO $3,800.
YOU ARE STILL IN THIRD PLACE,
THOUGH, BUT THAT'S GOOD NEWS
IN A WAY, BECAUSE YOU GET
TO GO FIRST IN DOUBLE JEOPARDY!
WHEN WE COME BACK.
RED IN PART BY...
IN A WAY, BECAUSE YOU GET
TO GO FIRST IN DOUBLE JEOPARDY!
APTIONING
SPONSORED IN PART BY...
WELCOME BACK,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
THIS MIGHT WELL
FALL INTO THE CATEGORY
OF ONE-UPSMANSHIP.
ON YESTERDAY'S PROGRAM,
YOU'LL RECALL THAT I MENTIONED
MY 91-YEAR-OLD MOTHER
WHO WAS SITTING IN THE AUDIENCE.
WELL, TODAY,
I WOULD LIKE YOU ALL TO GREET
THIS LOVELY LADY
WHO IS VISITING US,
AND SHE IS 102 YEARS OLD
AND A FAN OF "JEOPARDY!"
YOUNG AND OLD,
WE GET THEM ALL.
ALL RIGHT, BETH, YOU GET TO
SELECT FIRST IN DOUBLE JEOPARDY!
HERE ARE THE CATEGORIES
FOR YOU...
YOU HAVE TO NAME THE LARGEST
LAKE EACH CITY LIES ON,
OR IS NEAR...
NOT IDIOT. BETH.
ALL RIGHT,
LETTERS TO SANTA FOR $400.
WHO IS NERO?
LETTERS TO SANTA, $800.
WHO IS NAPOLéON?
LAKE CITY FOR $400.
WHAT IS ERIE?
LAKE CITY FOR $800.
WHAT IS LAKE TAHOE?
NO. BETH.
WHAT'S LAKE GEORGE?
NO.
WHAT IS LAKE MEAD?
JASON, GO AGAIN.
LAKE CITY FOR $1,200.
IT MIGHT WORK OUT
FOR YOU AFTER ALL.
YOU'RE STILL
IN THE LEAD.
YOU HAVE $2,400 MORE
THAN LESLIE.
$2,000, PLEASE.
OKAY...
WHAT IS LAKE VICTORIA?
THAT'S THE LAKE.
WHEW.
WHAT IS LAKE TITICACA?
LAKE CITY FOR $2,000.
WHAT IS THE CASPIAN?
$2,000 MORE FOR YOU.
UM, VILLAGE IDIOM 00.
FOR $4  WHAT'S A SQUARE PEG?
UH, VILLAGE IDIOM, $800.
WHAT IS THE FAT?
VILLAGE IDIOM, $1,200.
UH, WHAT IS BLOOD?
UH, VILLAGE IDIOM FOR $1,600.
WHAT IS YEOMEN?
VILLAGE IDIOM FOR $2,000.
THEY BOTH KNOW
WHERE THE BODIES ARE BURIED.
JASON, BACK TO YOU.
ETYMOLOGY FOR $400.
WHAT IS PATELLA?
ETYMOLOGY FOR $800.
WHAT IS HEARING?
ETYMOLOGY FOR $1,200.
WHAT IS THE COCCYX?
UH, $1,600, ETYMOLOGY.
WHAT IS DURA MATER?
ETYMOLOGY FOR $2,000.
HERE'S JIMMY
WITH THE CLUE.
THE HYOID
WHICH SUPPORTS THE TONGUE,
TAKES ITS NAME FROM
THE GREEK WORD HYOEIDES,
MEANING SHAPED LIKE
THE LOWERCASE FORM
OF THIS GREEK LETTER.
WHAT IS OMEGA?
NO. BETH OR LESLIE?
SHAPED LIKE A U.
WHAT IS UPSILON?
UPSILON.
BACK TO YOU, JASON.
LETTERS TO SANTA
FOR $1,200.
WHO IS MONTEZUMA?
AND HE GETS IT.
LETTERS TO SANTA FOR $1,600.
WHO IS RICHARD III?
UH, $2,000, LETTERS TO SANTA.
AND MY NAME IS RAMSES.
LESLIE, WE
COME BACK TO YOU.
TWO CATEGORIES
STILL UP THERE.
UH, STONY CATEGORY, $400.
WHAT IS
THE STATUE OF LIBERTY?
STONY CATEGORY FOR $800.
WHAT'S THE SUPREME COURT?
$1,200, STONY.
"DO NOT A PRISE."
LESLIE.
$1,600, STONY.
ON MAKUM...
AND YOU HAVE ENOUGH MONEY
TO OVERTAKE JASON.
I DO, AND THAT'S
NOT GOING TO HAPPEN.
I WILL WAGER $2,000, PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT,
HERE IS THE CL
UH, WHAT IS NEOLITHIC
AND PALEOLITHIC?
RIGHT YOU ARE.
$11,400 NOW,
AS YOU KEEP MOVING UP.
UH, STONY FOR $2,000, PLEASE.
FROM ABOUT
1,200 TO 400 B.C.,
THESE PEOPLE CARVED STONE HEADS,
LIKE THE ONE SEEN HERE,
AND LIVED ALONG
THE GULF OF MEXICO.
WHO ARE THE TOLTECS?
NO. JASON.
WHO ARE THE OLMEC?
WITH LESS THAN
A MINUTE TO GO.
STREEP TEASE FOR $400.
WHAT IS JULIA & JULIA?
"JULIE & JULIA."
NO.
YES, YOU CORRECTED YOURSELF
IN TIME,
AND THAT'S
GOOD NEWS FOR YOU.
GO AGAIN.
$2,000, PLEASE.
WHAT'S
"THE MANCHURIAN CANDIDATE"?
$1,600.
WHAT IS
"BRIDGES OF MADISON COUNTY"?
(beep)
OH, AND WITH THAT,
YOU MOVE UP TO $3,000.
LESLIE3,800.
JASON--$20,200,
WHICH MEANS
IT'S NOT A RUNAWAY.
SO IT'S STILL ANYONE'S GAME
AS WE GO INTO FINAL.
WE'LL BE BACK TO REVEAL
THE CLUE AFTER THIS.
SO IT'S STILL ANYONE'S GAME
AS WE GO INTO FINAL.
I'VE BEEN A SUPERINTENDENT
FOR 30 SOME YEARS AT MANY
DIFFERENT PARK SERVICE UNITS
ACROSS THE UNITED STATES
I'VE BEEN A SUPERINTENDENT
FOR 30 SOME YEARS AT MANY
THE ONLY TIME I'VE EVER
HAD A BREAK IS WHEN
I WAS ON MATERNITY LEAVE.
I HAVE RETIRED FROM DOING
THIS ONE THING THAT I LOVED.
. NOW, I'M GOING TO BE
ABLE TO HAVE THE TIME
TO EXPLORE SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
IT'S LIKE ANOTHER CHAPTER.
of Washington about the future
of Medicare and Social Security.
ANNCR: But you deserve straight
talk about the options on the...
table and what they mean for you
and your family.
ANCR: AARP is cutting throught.
Because for our 37 million
members, only one word counts.
Get the facts at earnedasay.org.
all keep Medicare...
and Social Security strong for
generations to come.
FOR OUR FINAL CATEGORY,
AS WE WRAP UP THE WEEK,
WORD HISTORY,
RE IS THE CLUE...
30 SECONDS, CONTESTANTS.
GOOD LUCK.
♪
BETH, TODAY, UNFORTUNATELY,
WAS NOT AS GOOD FOR YOU
AS WAS YESTERDAY,
BUT LET'S TAKE A LOOK
AT YOUR RESPONSE, SEE IF YOU
CAME UP WITH THE CORRECT ONE.
NO, YOU DIDN'T, AND IT'LL COST
YOU HOW MUCH OF THAT $3,000?
ALL OF IT,
SO YOU'RE AT ZERO.
LET'S GO DOWN TO LESLIE.
SHE HAD $13,800,
AND DID SHE COME UP WITH
THE WORD WE ARE SEEKING?
SHE SAID,
"WHAT IS A DEPENDENT?"
AND THAT IS INCORRECT.
YOUR WAGER WAS $
AND THAT
DROPS YOU DOWN TO $6,558.
TAKES US TO JASON KELLER.
WAS THE 16-YEAR WAIT
WORTH IT FOR HIM?
WHAT DID HE PUT DOWN?
"WHAT IS ADDICT?"
HE IS CORRECT,
AND HIS WAGER?
$8,000. $28,200.
THAT'S A PRETTY GOOD PAYDAY.
I GUESS IT WAS
WORTH IT AFTER ALL.
IT WAS.
ENJOY THE WEEKEND, JASON. WE'LL
SEE YOU BACK HERE ON MONDAY.
PLEASE JOIN US
ALSO, WON'T YOU?
SO LONG, EVERYBODY.
PROMOTIONAL CONSIDERATION
PROVIDED BY...
ANNOUNCER: TODAY ON "KATIE."
♪
ANNOUNCER: THE CAST OF "KATIE"
KATIE COURIC "JERSEY SHORE"
TAKES THEIR FINAL BOW.
IT'S TIME FOR SOME G.T.K.
GYM, TANNING AND KATIE
KATIE: DO YOU EVER