CLAIRE: IT'S PARTY
NIGHT, AND THAT USUALLY
MEANS A NIGHT THAT'S FUN
FOR EVERYONE BUT THE
HOST.
TODAY, I'VE GOT SOME
SIMPLE SOLUTIONS TO GET
SOME IMPRESSIVE PLATES
TO THE PARTY WITHOUT ALL
THE STRESS.
I LOVE THROWING PARTIES,
BUT THEY CAN BE A LOT OF
HARD WORK.
LUCKILY, I HAVE SOME
GREAT RECIPES THAT ARE
REALLY EASY TO MULTIPLY,
AND I'VE TESTED THEM OUT
ON MY FRIENDS, SO I KNOW
THAT THEY WILL FLY OFF
THE TABLE.
I'M STARTING WITH ONE OF
MY FAVORITE PARTY BITES,
MY SMASHED PEA AND
RICOTTA CROSTINI.
WHAT'S GREAT ABOUT THIS
DISH IS THAT IT'S SO
COLORFUL, SO IT'SFUL, AS WES
BEAUTIFUL, AS WELL AS
DELICIOUS.
IT'S ALSO A FAMILY
FAVORITE.
THE WOMEN IN MY FAMILY
LOVE IT.
AND WHEN YOU'RE THROWING
A PARTY, IT'S IMPORTANT
TO REMEMBER THAT VISUALS
ARE JUST AS IMPORTANT AS
FLAVOR.
SO, LET'S GET STARTED.
I HAVE MY WATER COMING
UP TO A BOIL.
I'M GOING TO ADD A
COMBINATION OF SALT AND
SUGAR.
THIS IS GOING TO MAKE
SURE THAT MY PEAS ARE
PERFECTLY SEASONED.
AND I'M ADDING SUGAR,
BECAUSE IT REALLY
EMPHASIZES THE NATURAL
SWEETNESS OF THE PEAS.
I'M USING FROZEN PEAS,
AND THE GREAT THING
ABOUT FROZEN IS THEN YOU
HAVE ACCESS TO
DELICIOUS-TASTING PEAS
ALL YEAR ROUND; PLUS,
IT'S SUPER CONVENIENT.
AND I'M JUST GOING TO
COOK THEM FOR ABOUT TWO
TO THREE MINUTES UNTIL
THEY GET NICE AND BRIGHT
GREEN.
MY PEAS LOOK DONE.
THEY'RE BEAUTIFUL,
THEY'RE BRIGHT, AND THEY
STILL HAVE THAT REALLY
NICE ROUNDNESS TO THEM.
YOU DON'T EY'RE
PUCKERED
LOOK LIKE THEY'RE
PUCKERED IN.
THAT MEANS THEY'RE
OVERCOOKED.
SO, I'M JUST GOING TO
DRAIN THESE OFF.
ALL RIGHT.
TO PUT THIS TOGETHER,
I'M GOING TO PUT ALL OF
MY INGREDIENTS IN THE
FOOD PROCESSOR, STARTING
WITH MY PEAS.
NEXT, I'M GOING TO ADD
MY RICOTTA AND THEN JUST
A LITTLE BIT OF MINT..
SO, I'M GOING TOLIGHTLY CHO.
AND EVEN THOUGH IT'S
GOING IN A FOOD
PROCESSOR, I'M CHOPPING
THIS, BECAUSE I DON'T
REALLY WANT TO OVER
PROCESS IT.
I WANT SOMETHING THAT'S
REALLY DELICIOUS AND
WELL-BLENDED, BUT NOT
BABY FOOD.
WELL, MY MINT LOOKS
READY.
I'M JUST GOING TO ADD
ABOUT TWO TEASPOONS OF
THIS -- NOT A LOT -- I
JUST WANT A HINT OF THE
MINT.
NEXT, I'M GOING TO ADD A
PINCH OF WHITE PEPPER.
I HAVE A LOT OF DELICATE
FLAVORS HAPPENING IN
THIS CROSTINI, SO I LIKE
USING WHITE PEPPER,
BECAUSE IT DOESN'T
OVERPOWER IT.
SO, I'M JUST GOING TO
LIGHTLY PULSE IT.
I DO NOT WANT TO
OVER-BLEND THIS OR PUREE
IT.
THAT IS IT.
I DO NOT WANT TO DO
ANYTHING ELSE TO THIS.
I'M GOING
I'M GOING TO ADJUST IT A
LITTLE BIT.
I'M GOING TO TASTE IT,
SEE IF IT NEEDS ANY SALT
AND PEPPER, AND THEN
MAYBE PULSE IT JUST ONE
TO TWO MORE
LET'S GIVE IT A TASTE,
SEE IF IT NEEDS ANY
ADJUSTMENT.
MM, THAT IS SUPER TASTY.
I LOVE WHITE PEPPER,
THOUGH, SO I'M JUST
GOING TO ADD A LITTLE
BIT MORE.
AND IT'S IMPORTANT TO
REMEMBER THAT I ALREADY
SEASONED MY PEAS, WHEN I
BOILED THEM, WITH SALT
AND SUGAR; SO I DON'T
HAVE TO REALLY ADD
ANYMORE SALT.
ALL RIGHT, JUST A COUPLE
OF PULSES TO BLEND THEM
TOGETHER.
WELL, THIS LOOKS GREAT.
I'M GOING TO GET IT INTO
A BOWL AND THEN WORK ON
THE REST OF MY CROSTINI.
MY PEAS ARE DONE, SO NOW.
I'M GOING TO MOVE OVER
TO MSO NOW.
CROSTINI JUST MEANS
TOAST, AND IT'S A
WONDERFUL THING TO USE
IN A PARTY, BECAUSE YOU
CAN MULTIPLY IT BY JUST
ADDING MORE BREAD, AND
GUESTS LOVE IT, BECAUSE
YOU DON'T GET YOUR
FINGERS MESSY WHEN YOU
EAT IT.
TO MAKE MY CROSTINI, IT
COULD NOT BE EASIER.
I'M GOING TO SLICE MY
BREAD PRETTY THIN.
I WANT IT TO BE EASY TO
BITE THROUGH AND ON A
BIAS, SO I GET LARGER
SLICES.
YOU CAN SEE I SLICED
THESE PRETTY THIN, AND
IT'S BECAUSE I DON'T
WANT MY GUESTS TO GET A
BIG BITE OF TOAST.
I WANT EVERYTHING TO BE
IN BALANCE.
SO NOW I'M JUST GOING TO
DRIZZLE THEM WITH A
LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL.
THIS GIVES THEM A REALLY
NICE COLOR AND CRISPS
THEM UP REALLY WELL.
NOW I'M JUST GOING TO
POP THEM IN THE OVEN
UNTIL THEY TURN A NICE
GOLDEN BROWN.
MY CROSTINI ARE DONE, SO
I'M GOING TO PUT ONE
TOGETHER AND GIVE IT A
TASTE.
YOU DON'T NEED A LOT;
JUST ONE SPOONFUL WILL
TOTALLY DO.
AND THEN I LIKE TO
FINISH THEM WITH A
FRAICHE, WHICH IS
FRAICHE, WHICH IS JUST
FRENCH SOUR CREAM, AND
IT'S A LITTLE BIT
THINNER, SO IT DRIZZLES
REALLY WELL.
YOU CAN ALWAYS ADD A
TOUCH OF MILK TO REGULAR
SOUR CREAM TO GET A
SIMILAR CONSISTENCY.
ALL RIGHT, I'M GOING TO
GIVE IT A TRY.
MM, THAT IS THE PERFECT
PARTY BITE.
IT IS SO GOOD.
I LOVE THE COMBINATION
OF THE CRUNCHY CROSTINI
WITH THE CREAMY SMASHED
PEAS AND THEN THE LITTLE
BIT OF TARTNESS FROM THE
CRÈME FRAICHE.
IT'S A REALLY GREAT
COMBINATION.
WHEN WE COME BACK, I'M
PUTTING A SOPHISTICATED
SPIN ON RUSTIC BEAN DIP,
SURE TO IMPRESS EVEN THE
BIGGEST FOODY.
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
At Yoplait,
we want you to feel
even better
about your favorite flavors.
So when you call, tweet,
and post, we listen.
That's why Yoplait Light
and Yoplait Original
are now made with
no high fructose corn syrup.
And why we use
only natural colors
and natural flavors
in Yoplait Original.
So, anything else we can do
for you, let us know.
But you'll keep it
to yogurt, right?
'Cause we shouldn't really help
with your love life.
Yoplait. It is so good!
CLAIRE: TODAY, WE'RE
PREPARING FOR PARTY
NIGHT.
I'M MAKING IT EASY ON
MYSELF BY MAKING NO-FUSS
PLATES THAT ARE STUNNING
ON THE TABLE.
I LOVE CANNELLINI BEANS.
THEY'RE REALLY TENDER
AND SOFT AND SO
DELICIOUS, ESPECIALLY
WHEN COMBINED WITH MY
ROASTED CHERRY TOMATOES.
THIS PLATTER IS SUCH A
WINNER AT EVERY PARTY I
TAKE IT TO.
I'M GOING TO GET STARTED
ON MY ROASTED CHERRY
TOMATOES, BECAUSE THEY
TAKE THE LONGEST, AND IT
COULD NOT BE SIMPLER.
I'M GOING TO TAKE MY
WHOLE CHERRY TOMATOES --
I DON'T NEED TO SLICE
THEM OR ANYTHI
JUST PUT THE
JUST PUT THEM ON MY
SHEET PAN.
NEXT, I ADD A LITTLE BIT
OF ROSEMARY, JUST SO
DELICIOUS AND EARTHY.
I'M JUST GOING TO PULL
THE LEAVES RIGHT OFF AND
JUST SPRINKLE THEM ON
TOP.
NEXT, I'M GOING TO
SPREAD THESE OUT AND ADD
MY OIL, AND I'M JUST
DRIZZLING IT.
IT'S JUST TO MAKE SURE
NOTHING STICKS.
THERE, THAT'S PLENTY.
NEXT, JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF SALT AND PEPPER TO
SEASON.
AND THEN SOME PEPPER.
AND USING MY HANDS, I'M
JUST GOING TO ROLL THEM
AROUND JUST TO MAKE SURE
EVERYTHING'S COATED.
WELL, THESE ARE READY TO
GO INTO THE OVEN.
WHILE MY TOMATOES ARE
ROASTING IN THE OVEN,
I'M GOING TO GET STARTED
ON MY CANNELLINI BEANS,
AND I LOVE THESE.
THEY HAVE A REALLY
BUTTERY, MEATY, HEARTY
FLAVOR THAT IS SO
DELICIOUS.
AND I'M DOING SOMETHING
A LITTLE DIFFERENT WITH
THEM TODAY.
I AM SAUTEEING THEM, SO
I'M GOING TO GIVE THEM A
REALLY DELICIOUS SORT OF
BLISTERED, GOLDEN BROWN
TEXTURE ON THE OUTSIDE,
BUT STILL WITH THAT
REALLY TENDER BITE ON
THE INSIDE.
SO, I'M GOING TO GET
STARTED.
I HAVE MY PAN HERE OVER
A MEDIUM FLAME.
I'M GOING TO ADD JUST A
LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL.
NEXT, I'M ADDING MY
GARLIC, AND I USUALLY
DON'T ADD GARLIC
STRAIGHT INTO OIL,
BECAUSE IT CAN BURN
REALLY EASILY, BUT I
REALLY WANT TO GET THAT
OIL FLAVOR WITH THE
GARLIC, SO I'M GOING TO
ADD IT IN BUT REALLY
WATCH IT.
NEXT, I'M ADDING MY
CHILI FLAKES JUST FOR A
LITTLE BIT OF HEAT.
AND WITH THE GARLIC AND
CHILI, YOU CAN ADD AS
MUCH OR AS LITTLE AS YOU
LIKE.
SO, I'M JUST GOING TO
LET THIS COOK UNTIL IT'S
BARELY TOASTED.
THAT LOOKS REALLY GOOD,
AND IT SMELLS AMAZING.
SO NOW I'M JUST GOING TO
ADD MY BEANS STRAIGHT
IN, AND I'M GOING TO
STIR THEM AROUND TO MAKE
SURE THEY'RE FULLY
COATED.
I WOULD TYPICALLY USE
DRY CANNELLINI BEANS,
BECAUSE THEN I CAN COOK
THEM MYSELF, BUT IT'S
PARTY NIGHT, AND I'M
KIND OF IN A HURRY, SO
CANNED IS JUST FINE.
NEXT, I'M GOING TO ADD
MY ROSEMARY, AND THIS IS
JUST SUCH A DELICIOUS
FLAVOR ON TOP OF THE
CANNELLINI BEANS.
SO, I JUST TURNED UP THE
HEAT A LITTLE BIT, AND
I'M GOING TO LET THESE
SIT UNDISTURBED FOR A
MINUTE OR TWO, JUST TO
MAKE SURE THEY GET NICE
AND GOLDEN BROWN
UNDERNEATH.
THESE LOOK GREAT, SO I'M
JUST GOING TO FLIP THEM
AND LET THEM COOK FOR
JUST A LITTLE BIT
LONGER.
AND YOU REALLY WANT TO
COOK THEM WELL, BECAUSE
YOU WANT THAT REALLY
GOLDEN BROWN, ALMOST
CRUNCHY EXTERIOR.
WELL, THESE LOOK READY,
SO I'M GOING TO TURN OFF
THE HEAT AND PUT THE
REST OF MY DISH
TOGETHER.
AND MY ROASTED CHERRY
TOMATOES SHOULD BE READY
BY NOW, SO I'M GOING TO
PULL THAT OUT OF THE
OVEN.
THOSE LOOK BEAUTIFUL!
SO NOW I'M JUST GOING TO
PUT MY PLATTER TOGETHER.
FIRST, I HAVE MY FRESH
MOZZARELLA, SO I'M JUST
GOING TO SLICE THIS UP,
AND I'M JUST GOING TO DO
THIN SLICES.
AND THEN I'M GOI
CHIFFONADE MY BASIL.
SO, I JUST LIKE TO STACK
IT ON TOP AND THEN ROLL
IT UP AND SLICE IT
REALLY THINLY.
ALL RIGHT, NOW I'M GOING
TO GET PLATING.
FIRST, I'M GOING TO GRAB
MY CANNELLINI BEANS.
I'M JUST GOING TO FILL
UP ONE SIDE OF MY
PLATTER.
AND NOW I'M FILLING THE
OTHER SIDE WITH MY
TOMATOES, AND I'M DOING
THIS BY HAND, BECAUSE IT
CAN BE A LITTLE
DELICATE.
ALSO, I LOVE THE FLAVOR
THAT COMES OUT WITH THE
ROASTED CHERRY TOMATOES.
THEY'RE JUST SUPER
SWEET, AND ALL THE BROWN
SPOTS TASTE KIND OF
CARAMELIZED.
OKAY, THAT LOOKS
BEAUTIFUL.
SO NOW I'M GOING TO TOP
IT WITH MY MOZZARELLA.
I'M JUST GOING TO FAN
THIS OUT ONE PIECE AT A
TIME.
NEXT, I'M GOING TO ADD
SOME LEMON ZEST, AND I
LIKE ADDING IT TO THIS
KIND OF DISH, BECAUSE
IT'S AN UNEXPECTED
FLAVOR.
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
THAT LOOKS PERFECT.
AND THEN A LITTLE BIT OF
MY BASIL RIGHT ON TOP.
I DON'T WANT TO COVER
THE ENTIRE DISH.
I WANT TO BE ABLE TO SEE
ALL OF THE DIFFERENT
INGREDIENTS.
THIS LOOKS GORGEOUS, BUT
I THINK IT COULD USE
JUST A LITTLE DRIZZLE OF
OLIVE OIL.
IT ADDS A NICE SHEEN AND
REALLY BRINGS IT ALL
TOGETHER.
THIS A TAS
THIS A TASTE.
I WANT TO GET A LITTLE
BIT OF EVERYTHING.
AND THIS IS PERFECT FOR
A PARTY, BECAUSE IT'S
JUST A FAMILY STYLE
PLATTER.
EVERYBODY CAN GRAB A
LITTLE BIT OF WHATEVER
THEY FEEL LIKE EATING
AND DIG IN.
MM, THAT IS SO, SO GOOD.
I LOVE THE CANNELLINI
BEANS.
THEY'RE REALLY MEATY AND
KIND OF BUTTERY, AND
THEN THE ROASTED
TOMATOES ADD JUST A
LITTLE BIT OF SWEETNESS,
AND THE FRESH MOZZARELLA
IS REALLY CREAMY.
IS REALL
THIS IS A WONDERFUL
COMBINATION AND PERFECT
FOR A PARTY.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
WHAT'S A PARTY WITHOUT
FINGER FOOD?
I'M MAKING AN EASY AND
DELICIOUS TAKE ON A
TYPICAL HAM SANDWICH
THAT FLIES OFF THE PLATE
EVERY TIME I SERVE IT.
[ Woman ] Ring. Ring.
Progresso.
In what world do potatoes,
bacon and cheese
add up to 100 calories?
Your world.
♪
[ whispers ]
Real bacon...
Creamy cheese...
100 calories...
[ Chef ] Ma'am
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
CLAIRE: IT'S PARTY
NIGHT, AND IT ISN'T
COMPLETE WITHOUT FINGER
FOOD.
EASY TO MAKE AND EASY TO
MAKE MORE OF, MY SWISS
CHARD AND PROSCIUTTO
SANDWICHES ARE THE HITS
OF ANY GET-TOGETHER.
THESE SANDWICHES ARE
BASICALLY A FANCY
VERSION OF GRILLED
CHEESE.
THEY'RE EASY TO MAKE AND
EVEN EASIER TO MULTIPLY.
BEFORE I GET ON THE
STOVE AND START GRILLING
THESE SANDWICHES, I HAVE
TO FINISH PREPPING MY
INGREDIENTS, AND ONE OF
THEM IS SWISS CHARD.
I LOVE THIS STUFF.
IT'S SORT SOMEWHERE BETWEEN
SOMEWHERE BETWEEN
SPINACH AND KALE, SO
IT'S A LITTLE HEARTIER
THEN SPINACH, BUT HAS A
MORE DELICATE FLAVOR
THAN KALE.
IT'S REALLY LOVELY IN
THIS COMBINATION OF
PROSCIUTTO AND CHEESE,
AND IT BRINGS THAT
REALLY KIND OF EARTHY
GREEN FLAVOR.
SO, I HAVE MY SWISS
CHARD HERE READY TO
BREAK DOWN.
I'VE ALREADY WASHED IT
OFF, AND THEN I JUST
HAVE TO REMOVE THIS RIB,
WHICH IS BASICALLY A
STALK ALONG THE BACK.
THE EASIEST WAY TO DO IT
IS JUST TAKE YOUR KNIFE
AND WORK IT RIGHT ALONG
THE RIB, AND THEN I'M
JUST GOING TO CHOP IT
UP.
SO, I'M JUST GOING TO
ROLL THIS UP, SIMILAR TO
WHAT I DID WITH MY BASIL
EARLIER, BUT JUST IN
LARGER SECTIONS.
I'M JUST GOING TO SLICE
IT THROUGH LIKE THIS AND
THEN ONCE DOWN THE
MIDDLE.
THIS WILL COOK DOWN A
LOT WHEN I SAUTEE IT.
THIS LOOKS READY.
I'M GOING TO TAKE THIS
BACK AND SAUTEE IT AND
THEN GET STARTED ON MY
SANDWICHES.
SO TO START, I HAVE MY
PAN OVER A MEDIUM LOW
HEAT.
I'M JUST GOING TO ADD A
LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL
JUST TO MAKE SURE
NOTHING STICKS.
AND THEN I'M ADDING MY
GARLIC.
AND BECAUSE GARLIC CAN
BURN REALLY EASILY, I AM
GOING TO KEEP AN EYE ON
IT.
I'M JUST GOING TO WAIT
UNTIL IT GETS BARELY
GOLDEN.
THIS LOOKS GREAT, SO I'M
GOING TO ADD MY CHARD.
AND IT LOOKS LIKE A LOT
RIGHT NOW, BUT THIS IS
GOING TO COOK DOWN.
I'M GOING TO MIX IT
TOGETHER.
I WANT TO MAKE SURE IT'S
ALL EVENLY COATED IN THE
OIL AND GARLIC.
NOW I'M GOING TO ADD A
PINCH OF SALT AND
PEPPER.
I'M GOING TO LET THIS DO
ITS THING FOR A FEW
MINUTES MORE.
I'M JUST GOING TO STIR
IT TO MAKE SURE IT COOKS
BUT DOESN'T BURN.
THIS LOOKS DONE.
YOU CAN TELL, BECAUSE
IT'S A REALLY BEAUTIFUL
DARK SHADE OF GREEN, BUT
IT DOESN'T LOOK BLACK OR
BROWN OR SUPER DARK.
MY SWISS CHARD IS DONE,
SO NOW I'M GOING TO PUT
TOGETHER MY SANDWICHES.
SO, I'M GOING TO TAKE
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF MY
SWISS CHARD AND PUT IT
RIGHT ON THE BOTTOM, AND
A LITTLE GOES A LONG
WAY.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO REALLY
PILE IT UP.
OKAY, NEXT I'M GOING TO
ADD JUST A LITTLE BIT OF
PROSCIUTTO.
NEXT, I'M GOING TO ADD A
SLICE OF GRUYERE, AND
GRUYERE IS VERY SIMILAR
TO SWISS.
IT JUST HAS A FULLER,
SLIGHTLY SHARPER FLAVOR.
IT GOES GREAT AGAINST
THE PROSCIUTTO.
AND THEN JUST A FEW
LEAVES OF PARSLEY JUST
RIGHT ON TOP.
AND I LOVE WHAT PARSLEY
BRINGS TO THIS DISH,
BECAUSE IT ADDS A LITTLE
BIT OF FRESHNESS,
ESPECIALLY WITH THE
MELTING CHEESE AND THEN
THE PROSCIUTTO.
IT'S REALLY NICE TO HAVE
THAT.
AND THEN MY BREAD.
I'M GOING TO BUILD A
COUPLE MORE, AND THEN
I'LL BE READY TO GRILL.
WELL, MY SANDWICHES ARE
ALL MADE.
ALL I HAVE TO DO IS
GRILL THEM.
AND I'M TREATING THIS
EXACTLY LIKE A GRILLED
CHEESE SANDWICH.
I HAVE MY SKILLET OVER
MEDIUM HEAT.
I'M GOING TO ADD A
LITTLE BIT OF OLIVE OIL
JUST TO GREASE UP THE
PAN, AND IT ALSO MAKES
THE BREAD REALLY GOLDEN
BROWN.
I'M GOING TO POP THESE
RIGHT ON TOP.
WITH A RECIPE LIKE THIS,
YOU WANT TO KEEP IT AT
MEDIUM OR MEDIUM LOW.
YOUR GOAL IS FOR GOLDEN
BROWN BREAD AND MELTED
CHEESE, NOT BURNT BREAD
AND COLD CHEESE.
WITH GRILLED CHEESE, YOU
REALLY ONLY WANT TO FLIP
ONCE, AND THESE ARE
GOLDEN BROWN ON THE
BOTTOM, SO THEY ARE
READY.
SO NOW I'M GOING TO WAIT
UNTIL THEY GET GOLDEN
BROWN ON THE OTHER SIDE.
WELL, THESE ARE READY.
I CAN'T WAIT TO GIVE
THEM A TRY.
THESE LOOK GORGEOUS.
I CANNOT WAIT TO GIVE
THEM A BITE.
SO, I'M GOING TO BE
SLICING THESE ON THE
DIAGONAL, SO THAT PEOPLE
CAN EAT THEM AS LITTLEY SNA.
PARTY SNACKS.
SO, YOU CAN SERVE THEM
SMALLER FOR
SMALLER BITES, CUT THEM
INTO QUARTERS.
TIME TO GIVE IT A TASTE.
MM, THAT IS A REALLY
TASTY SANDWICH.
THE GRUYERE IS REALLY
MELTY AND RICH AND
DELICIOUS, AND IT GOES
PERF
PROSCIUTTO THAT HAS SORT
OF A MUSTY SWEETNESS,
AND THEN THE SWISS CHARD
GIVES THIS REALLY GREAT
GREEN, EARTHY FLAVOR.
I LOVE THIS COMBINATION,
AND IT'S A PERFECT PARTY
SNACK.
WHEN WE COME BACK, MY
FRIEND AND PARTY EXPERT,
WHITNEY, IS JOINING ME
TO HELP ME PREPARE FOR
PARTY NIGHT.
HI, I'M PHIL MICKELSON.
I'VE BEEN FORTUNATE TO WIN
ON GOLF'S BIGGEST STAGES.
BUT WHEN JOINT PAIN
AND STIFFNESS
FROM PSORIATIC ARTHRITIS HIT,
EVEN THE SMALLEST THINGS
BECAME DIFFICULT.
I FINALLY UNDERSTOOD WHAT
SERIOUS JOINT PAIN IS LIKE.
I TALKED TO MY RHEUMATOLOGIST
AND HE PRESCRIBED Enbrel.
Enbrel CAN HELP RELIEVE
PAIN, STIFFNESS,
AND STOP JOINT DAMAGE.
BECAUSE Enbrel, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS,
SOMETIMES FATAL EVENTS
INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS,
LYMPHOMA, OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING Enbrel,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START Enbrel IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON Enbrel, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING, OR PALENESS.
[ Phil ]
GET BACK TO THE THINGS
THAT MATTER MOST.
ASK YOUR RHEUMATOLOGIST
IF Enbrel IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
[ Doctor ]
Enbrel, THE NUMBER ONE
BIOLOG MEDICINE
PRESCRIBED BY RHEUMATOLOGISTS.
...and now...
You!
[ giggles ]
♪ The one and only, Cheerios
CLAIRE: I'M HERE TODAY
WITH MY LOVELY FRIEND
AND PARTY EXPERT,
WHITNEY ADAMS, AND SHE
HAS COME BY TO HELP ME
GET ORGANIZED.
WHITNEY: YES, WHEN I'M
THROWING A PARTY, ONE OF
THE MOST IMPORTANT
THINGS IS TO GREET YOUR
GUESTS WITH SOMETHING TO
EAT OR TO DRINK.
IT KEEPS THEM WELL FED
AND OCCUPIED WHILE
YOU'RE PUTTING TOGETHER
THE FINISHING TOUCHES.
CLAIRE: WELL, THEN,
TRYING TO START OFF ON
THE RIGHT FOOT, SO HERE
YOU GO.
WHITNEY: EXCELLENT WORK,
CLAIRE.
CLAIRE: SMASHED PEAS
WITH RICOTTA, A LITTLE
BIT OF MINT, AND THEN
CRÈME FRAICHE DRIZZLED
ON TOP, SO REALLY
REFRESHING.
WHITNEY: NICE, ALL
RIGHT.
MM.
MM-HM.
CLAIRE: MM-HM.
WHITNEY: MM-HM.
CLAIRE: SO, IS THIS
WHITNEY PARTY FRIENDLY?
WHITNEY: OH, MY
GOODNESS, MM-HM.
[CLAIRE LAUGHING]
.T IS WHITNEY
APPROVED.T IS WHITN
THAT'S OFFICIAL.
CLAIRE: FANTASTIC.
WHITNEY: CRUNCHY, SOFT,
SWEET AND SALTY, REALLY
GOOD.
CLAIRE: THANK YOU.
SO, WHAT OTHER PARTY
TIPS WOULD YOU
RECOMMEND?
WHITNEY: IT'S ALWAYS
NICE TO HAVE A COUPLE OF
SNACKS AROUND, NO MATTER
WHAT THE MEAL LOOKS
LIKE.
I THINK NUTS ARE A GREAT
THING TO HAVE, AND
POPCORN IS ANOTHER THING
THAT YOU CAN DO.
CLAIRE: OH.
WHITNEY: AND I KNOW YOU
DEFINITELY KNOW YOUR WAY
AROUND SOME POPCORN, SO --
CLAIRE: I LOVE POPCORN.
WHITNEY: RIGHT, AND
THOSE ARE TWO THINGS YOU
CAN KIND OF PRESENT IN
UNIQUE WAYS.
CLAIRE: MM-HM.
WHITNEY: I LOVE LITTLE
CHAMPAGNE COUPES, AND
WHEN YOU'RE
REPLENISHING, SAY, THE
CR
THOSE
THOSE OUT AND GET
PEOPLE'S MINDS OFF OF
THE FACT THAT THERE IS
NO LONGER ANY DELICIOUS
CROSTINI IN FRONT OF
THEM AND KEEP THEIR
MOUTHS BUSY, SO --
CLAIRE: WELL, GOOD TIP.
SO, LET'S DIG INTO
SOMETHING ELSE.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
WHITNEY: YES, I
DEFINITELY WANT TO TRY
THIS ONE.
CLAIRE: OOH, YES, YES,
YES, THE BLISTERED
CANNELLINI BEANS AND
FRESH MOZZARELLA AND
THEN ROASTED TOMATOES,
REALLY FRESH FLAVORS.
AND I WILL PUT
MOZZARELLA ON
PRACTICALLY ANYTHING.
WHITNEY: YES, IT'S
DELICIOUS, AND IT'S GOT
THE RIGHT AMOUNT OF
HEAT.
IT'S PERFECT.
CLAIRE: WELL, THANK YOU
SO MUCH FOR ALL OF THESE
HELPFUL TIPS.
THIS IS GOING TO MAKE MY
PARTY GO SO MUCH
SMOOTHER.
WHITNEY: OH, YOU'RE VERY
WELCOME.
I'M GLAD I COULD HELP.
AND ANY TIME YOU'RE
COOKING, I WILL BE
THERE.
THAT'S FOR SURE.
CLAIRE: WELL, THANK YOU.
THANKS FOR JOINING US ON
ANOTHER EPISODE OF FOOD
FOR THOUGHT.
TUNE IN NEXT WEEK FOR
MORE DELICIOUS AND
INSPIRING RECIPES.
I have high blood pressure.
And when I get a cold I take
Coricidin HBP.
The number one pharmacist
recommended cold brand
designed for people with high
blood pressure.
Coricidin HBP.
♪ MUSIC
>> Announcer: THE FOLLOWING IS A
PAID PROGRAM FOR THE NINJA MEGA
KITCHEN SYSTEM, BROUGHT TO YOU
BY EURO-PRO.
WHAT IN THE WORLD IS HAPPENING
TO US?
72 MILLION OF US ARE OVERWEIGHT
OR OBESE.
THERE'S EPIDEMIC DIABETES AMONG
OUR KIDS.
WE'RE GETTING SICK AND DYING
FROM EATING TOO MANY FOODS THAT
ARE OVERPROCESSED, LOW IN
NUTRIENTS AND FIBER AND HIGH IN
FAT AND CALORIES.
>> WHEN I WEIGHED 360 POUNDS,
YOU KNOW, IT'S THE OLD ADAGE,
"YOU ARE WHAT YOU EAT," AND I
WAS EATING GARBAGE AND MY HEALTH
WAS GARBAGE.
AND WHEN I CHANGED HOW I ATE AND
HOW I TREATED MY BODY, MY ENTIRE
HEALTH CHANGED.
I THINK THE REASON THAT A LOT OF
PEOPLE DON'T EAT HEALTHY IS
BECAUSE IT'S NOT CONVENIENT, AND
THE WONDERFUL THING ABOUT THE
NINJA IS IT MAKES IT CONVENIENT.