'Cause we shouldn't really help
with your love life.
Yoplait. It is so good!
>>> I AM VERY MINDFUL THAT
MERE WORDS CAN THOUGHT MATCH
THE DEPTHS OF YOUR SORROW.
>> THE PRESIDENT JOINS A
COMMUNITY IN MOURNING
TONIGHT.
GOOD EVENING.
I'M AMA DATES.
PRESIDENT OBAMA VISITED THE
GRIEF-STRICKEN COMMUNITY OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT WHERE HE
MET WITH THE VICTIMS'
FAMILIES.
HE WILL HAVE MORE ON TONIGHT'S
SERVICES IN A FEW MINUTES.
WE BEGIN WITH ABC NEWS
REPORTER LAURA ANTHONY LIVE IN
THE COMMUNITY STILL REELING
FROM THE SHOOTING THAT TOOK 27
LIVES.
LAURA?
>> Reporter: THAT'S RIGHT,
AMA.
THE COMMUNITY IS STILL REELING
AND STARTING TO HEAL A LITTLE
BIT.
IN THE MEANTIME WE LEARNED NEW
INFORMATION.
WE LEARNED ADAM LANZA, THE
SHOOTER, AND HIS MOTHER WHO
WAS A GUNNEN ENTHUSIAST.
ABC NEWS HAS LEARNED THAT SHE
ACTUALLY VISITED A GUN RANGE
IN THIS AREA ON SEVERAL
OCCASIONS.
AND WE LEARNED ON ONE OCCASION
SHE BROUGHT HER SON ADAM WITH
HER.
NOW, IT IS UNCLEAR AT THIS
POINT WHETHER HE FIRED ANY
GUNS THERE.
>> Reporter: THE GRIEVING
CONTINUED LATE INTO THE NIGHT
IN THE TINY NEW ENGLAND
VILLAGE OF SANDY HOOK, A
COMMUNITY STILL TRYING TO COME
TO GRIPS WITH ALL THEY LOST.
IN THE CENTER OF TOWN NEAR THE
CHRISTMAS TREE, THE MEMORIAL
GROWS TO THE 26 PEOPLE KILLED
BY ADAM LANZA AT THE LOCAL
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL TWO DAYS
AGO.
MANY CAME WITH THEIR KIDS.
>> HOW DO YOU FEEL?
>> I FEEL FINE, BUT I'M NOT
SCARED.
I'M STRONG.
>> ALL DAY PEOPLE HERE HAVE
BEEN TRYING TO STAY STRONG.
>> MOST OF THEM HAVE BEEN
CRYING .
>> MARCY OWNS FUN CUTS IN THE
VILLAGE.
ONE OF HER APPOINTMENTS FAILED
TO SHOW UP YESTERDAY.
HE WAS ONE OF THE LITTLE BOYS
KILLED AT THE SCHOOL.
>> THEY WOULD JUST -- THEY
WERE JUST ADORABLE, HAPPY,
FUNNY KIDS.
>> AND TODAY EVEN MORE
DISTURBING DETAILS EMERGED
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY.
STATE POLICE REVEAL LANZA
FIRED HUNDREDS OF ROUNDS IN
THE CLASSROOMS KILLING 20
FIRST GRADERSERS AND THE
PRINCIPAL.
AND THEN THERE WERE BULLETS HE
DIDN'T FIRE AND HUNDREDS MORE
LEFT BEHIND IN 30-ROUND
MAGAZINES AND STILL NOMO
TIFF.
NO MOTIVE.
>> WE DON'T HAVE A SPECIFIC
REASON TO SAY WHY THIS
OCCURRED.
>> WHATEVER THE REASON FOR THE
RAMPAGE, IT WILL NEVER MAKE
SENSE TO THIS COMMUNITY.
STILL JUST BEGINNING TO
REALIZE THE UNIMAGINABLE.
>> IT IS UNBELIEVABLE.
I JUST CAN'T IMAGINE GOING
HOME WITHOUT HIM.
>> NOW, TOMORROW IN THE
GREATER NEWTON AREA THERE WILL
STILL BE NO SCHOOL AT ANY OF
THE SCHOOLS.
ON TUESDAY WE UNDERSTAND ALL
CLASSES WILL RESUME AT ALL
SCHOOLS EXCEPT SANDY HOOK.
AND THEN THOSE CHILDREN AT
SOME TIME WILL RETURN TO
CLASSES, BUT NOT AT THAT
LOCATION.
IT WILL BE AT ANOTHER LOCATION
AT A NEIGHBORING VILLAGE.
LAURA ANTHONY, ABC NEWS.
>>> RESIDENTS OF NEWTOWN
GRIEVED AT AN INTER FAITH
MEMORIAL SERVICE WITH
PRESIDENT OBAMA IN ATTENDANCE
AT NEWTOWN HOSPITAL.
THEY SPOKE OF RECOVERY AND
CHANGE.
>> WE NEEDED THIS.
WE THEY'DED TO BE TOGETHER --
WE NEEDED TO BE TOGETHER HERE
IN THIS ROOM, IN THE
GYMNASIUM, OUTSIDE THE DOORS
OF THIS SCHOOL IN LIVING ROOMS
AROUND THE WORLD.
WE NEEDED TO BE TOGETHER.
>> THE HORROR THAT WAS VISITED
UPON OUR SANDY HOOKS SCHOOL
WAS NOT DESERVED.
IT IS THE ANGRY AND DESPERATE
ACT OF A CONFUSED YOUNG MAN.
>> 900 PEOPLE PACKED THE HIGH
SCHOOL GYM.
GROWN MEN CRIED HUGGING FIRST
RESPONDERS AND OTHERS FOUND A
CHANCE TO RELEASED PENNED UP
EMOTIONS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA PROMISED
CHANGE.
>> THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
AND TO END THEM WE MUST
CHANGE.
IN THE COMING WEEKS I WILL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE
HOLDS IN AN EFFORT AIMED AT
PREVENTING MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE
THIS.
>> FUNERALS HAVE BEEN
ANNOUNCED FOR SEVEN OF THE 27
VICTIMS.
THE FIRST TWO WILL BE
TOMORROW.
SERVICES ALL OVER THE BAY AREA
HONORED THE VICTIMS OF THE
SHOOTING.
WHAT LOCAL PEOPLE ARE DOING TO
REMEMBER THE VICTIMS, AND WHAT
YOU CAN DO TO MAKE A
DIFFERENCE.
>>> OUT OF THE TRAGEDY AT
SANDY HOOKS ELEMENTARY THERE
IS A STORY OF SURVIVAL.
A LITTLE GIRL WHOSE INSTINCTS
TOLD HER TO PLAY DEAD WHEN THE
GUNMAN BURST IN THE CLASS M
RUE.
SHE WAS THE ONLY ONE TO MAKE
IT OUT ALIVE.
>> SHE WAS THE FIRST STUDENT
WHO RAN OUT OF THE SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL, SIX AND A HALF YEARS
OLD.
SHE RAN OUT COVERED IN BLOOD
FROM HEAD TO TOE AND THE FIRST
WORDS SHE SAID WAS, MOMMY, I'M
OKAY, BUT ALL OF MY FRIENDS
ARE DEAD.
>> THE LITTLE GIRL IS ALREADY
SUFFERING SURVIVOR'S GUILT.
WE ARE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE
20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER.
LILIAN KIM SPOKE WITH ADAM
LANZA'S FORMER BABY-SITTER.
LILIAN WHAT HAVE YOU LEARNED?
>> I SPOKE WITH RYAN CRAFT AND
HE SAID HE DIDN'T KNOW ADAM
LANZA WELL, BUT NEITHER DID
ANYONE ELSE.
HE DOES HAVE VIVID MEMORIES OF
HIS TIME BABY-SITTING.
HE GREW UP TWO HOUSES DOWN
FROM THE LANZA'S AND HE EVEN
BABY SAT ADAM A HANDFUL OF
TIMES A DECADE AGO WHEN ADAM
WAS 10.
>> ADAM STRUCK ME AS AN
INTROVERTED KID.
HUEY WAS REALLY -- HE WAS
REALLY, REALLY QUIET.
WHEN WE WERE BUILDING LEGOS OR
DOING VIDEO GAMES HE WAS
REALLY FOCUSED ON IT.
IT WAS LIKE HE WAS IN HIS OWN
WORLD.
>> BEYOND THAT HE DIDN'T
NOTICE RED FLAGS OR VIOLENT
TENDONS SEES.
TENDENCIES.
BUT HE REMEMBERS HIS MOM,
NANCY, GIVING HIM STRICT
INSTRUCTIONS JAY SHE ALWAYS
TOLD ME TO KEEP MY EYE ON HIM
AT ALL TIMES AND NEVER TURN MY
BACK ON HIM EVEN FOR A
SECOND.
>> THEY REMOVED COMPUTERS FROM
THE HOME THIS WEEKEND WHICH
COULD PROVIDE IMPORTANT CLUES
TO THE MONTHY TIFF BEHIND THE
SHOOTING.
-- MOTIVE BEHIND THE
>> I DON'T THINK ANYONE WAS
AFRAID OF HIM.
THERE WERE A LOT OF PEOPLE WHO
JUST SAW HIM AS SOMEONE
DIFFERENT AND REALLY JUST LEFT
HIM ALONE.
>> AS FOR NANCY LANZA SHE WAS
ACTIVE.
IT WAS CLEAR THAT ADAM'S
ISSUES WAS TAKING A TOLL.
HE WAS A REGULAR AT THIS BAR
IN NEWTOWN AND ACCORDING TO
OWNERS IT WAS DIFFICULT FOR
HER TO GET ADAM TO FIND HIS
PLACE IN SOCIETY, BUT NO
WARNING ON VIOLENCE.
>> THERE WAS NEVER ANY TALK
ABOUT HIM BEING VIOLENT OR ANY
SUICIDAL TENDENCIES.
SHE NEVER EVER SPOKE OF
ANYTHING BAD.
>> AS FOR RYAN CRAFT, HIS
FORMER BABY-SITTER, HE HAS
ORGANIZED A FUNDRAISER THAT
ALREADY RAISED $50,000 FROM A
THOUSAND DONORS.
THIS THE NEWSROOM, LILIAN KIM,
ABC7 NEWS.
>> THANK YOU, LILIAN.
>>> COMING UP AT 11:30, WHY
DESPITE THE CRIES FOR CHANGE,
MORE PEOPLE THAN EVER ARE
BUYING GUNS.
>>> WITH CLASSES RESUMING
TOMORROW, SCHOOL DISTRICT USA
CROSS THE BAY AREA ARE
REMINDING EMPLOYEES OF THE
SAFETY MEASURES AND CALMING
PARENTS' NERVES.
SERGIO QUEEN -- QUINTANA HAS
MORE.
>> THERE WILL NO DOUBT BE TALK
ABOUT THE SHOOTINGS AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY.
THAT'S WHY THE TEACHER'S UNION
N%NT OUT THIS E-MAIL BLAST TO
THE MEMBERS.
IT IS A GUIDE TO HELP STEER
THE CONVERSATIONS.
>> I THINK IT IS VERY
IMPORTANT THAT PEOPLE KNOW
THAT CHILDREN ARE HELPED BY
HONESTLY TALKING ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED.
>> PRESIDENT DENNIS KELLY SAYS
CONVERSATIONS AT SCHOOL SHOULD
BE A CONTINUATION OF
CONVERSATIONS PARENTS HAVE
ALREADY HAD OVER THE WEEKEND.
>> THE PARENTS ARE GOING TO BE
TALKING TO THEIR CHILDREN AND
THE TEACHERS WILL BE TALKING
TO THE CHILDREN, AND CHILDREN
WILL BE TALKING TO CHILDREN.
ON THE PLAYGROUND THEY WILL BE
HEARING ABOUT THIS AND TALKING
ABOUT IT.
>> AND FOR THOSE PARENTS WHO
HAVE NOT TALKED WITH THEIR
CHILDREN, THE DEAN OF
PSYCHOLOGY AT SANTA CLARA
RECOMMENDS PARENTS SORT OUT
THEIR OWN FEELINGS ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED BEFORE HAVING THAT
CONVERSATION.
>> BECAUSE A CHILD WILL PICK
UP AND MODEL WHAT THE PARENTS
ARE EXPERIENCING.
AS A PARENT IF I AM
EXPERIENCING ANXIETY OR
SHOWING A LOT OF FEAR, THE
CHILD WILL PICK UP ON THAT.
>> SOME SCHOOL DISTRICTS HAVE
ALSO REACHED OUT TO POLICE
DEPARTMENTS IN THEIR COMMUNITY
TO REVIEW SAFETY PROCEDURES,
BUT FOR OTHER DISTRICTS LIKE
IN OAKLAND, THE THREAT OF
VIOLENCE IS SOMETHING THEY
DEAL WITH ON A REGULAR BASIS.
>> IN RECENT YEARS ON AVERAGE
THERE HAVE BEEN ABOUT 20
SCHOOL AGE CHILDREN THAT ARE
KILLED IN OAKLAND OR THAT
SUFFER VIOLENT DEATHS OVER THE
COURSE OF THE SCHOOL YEAR.
>> THEIR TEAM OF SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGISTS, COUNSELORS AND
MEMBERS OF THE POLICE FORCE
WILL BE ESPECIALLY AWARE
COMMON DAY MORNING.
ABC7 NEWS.
>> STAY WITH ABC7 NEWS FOR
CONTINUING COVERAGE OF THE
SCHOOL TRAGEDY.
WE WILL HAVE THE LATEST
UPDATES ON OUR WEBSITE,
ABC7NEWS.COM AND ON THE ABC
MORNING NEWS AT 4:30 A.M.
>>> LET'S GET TO LEIGH GLASER
FOR A FIRST CHECK ON WEATHER
AND WHAT IS GOING ON.
LEIGH?
[NO A YOU HAD YOW].
>> -- [NO AUDIO].
>> LEIGH, WE ARE HAVING A
LITTLE PROBLEM WITH YOUR
MICROPHONE SO WE WILL HAVE
MORE COMING UP.
>>> NAPA ROAD WILL REMAIN
CLOSED DUE TO AN ACCIDENT.
IT IS CLOSED IN BOTH
DIRECTIONS BETWEEN STONE CREST
DRIVE AND HAGAN ROAD.
THE CLOSURE WAS CAUSED BY AN
ACCIDENT THAT KNOCKED DOWN
POWER LINES.
IT IS EXPECTED TO REOPEN
AROUND 7:00 TOMORROW MORNING.
STILL TO COME ON ABC7 NEWS AT
11:00, A DEADLY TRAIN ACCIDENT
AFFECTED TRAFFIC THIS
EVENING.
WHERE AND WHAT YOU CAN
EXPECT.
PLUS SOUTHWEST SETTLES A
MULTIMILLION-DOLLAR CLASS
ACTION LAWSUIT.
ARE YOU ON THE RECEIVING END?
THAT'S TONIGHT ON ABC NEWS AT
11:00.
AND STEPPING OUT.
THE DUCHESS OF CAMBRIDGE'S
FIRST PUBLIC APPEARANCE SINCE
>>> THE DUCHESS OF CAME BRAG
MADE HER -- CAMBRIDGE MADE HER
FIRST APPEARANCE SINCE HER
HOSPITALIZATION.
THE FORMER KATE MIDDLETON WAS
A PRESENTER AT A SPORTS SHOW
IN LONDON.
THE DUCHESS SEEMED COMPOSED
AND COMFORTABLE.
SHE AND PRINCE WILLIAM ARE
EXPECTING THEIR FIRST CHILD.
THE DUCHESS WAS HOSPITALIZED
FOR ACUTE MORNING SICKNESS.
>>> DEPUTIES ARE INVESTIGATING
A FATAL COLLISION BETWEEN A
PEDESTRIAN AND TRAIN NEAR
HAYWARD.
IT HAPPENED NEAR WEST BLOSSOM
WAY AND TIMES AVENUE AROUND
7:00.
th IS JUST OUTSIDE THE
HAYWARD CITY LIMITS.
THE TRACKS WERE SHUTDOWN WHILE
AUTHORITIES INVESTIGATED.
THE AUTHORITIES HAVE NOT
RELEASED THE IDENTITY OF THE
VICTIM.
>>> TWO PEOPLE MANAGED TO WALK
AWAY FROM A CAR FIRE TODAY.
ALAN WANG SHOT THIS VIDEO.
HE WAS THERE BEFORE THE FIRE
DEPARTMENT ARRIVED ON SCENE.
THE ACCIDENT HAPPENED JUST
BEFORE 4:00 THIS AFTERNOON.
THE DRIVER LOST CONTROL WHILE
EXITING HIGHWAY 24 AT FISH
RANCH ROAD.
THE EXIT WAS CLOSED FOR
AWHILE, BUT IS OPEN TONIGHT.
>>> DISCUSSION ABOUT A
CONTROVERSIAL SOCCER FIELD
PROJECT IN SAN RAFAEL
CONTINUES WHEN THE CITY
COUNCIL MEETS TOMORROW NIGHT.
THE PROPOSED COMPLEX AT THE
SAN RAFAEL AIRPORT IS OPPOSED
BY ENVIRONMENTAL GROUPS AND
SOME RESIDENTS.
CONCERNS INCLUDE THE IMPACT ON
WILDLIFE AND AIRPORT SAFETY
ISSUES.
SUPPORTERS SAY THE CITY NEEDS
MORE ATHLETIC FIELDS.
IT IS SUPPORTED BY A 5 TO 1
VOTE BY THE PLANNING
COMMISSION.
>>> SOUTHWEST AIRLINES SETTLED
A LAWSUIT WORTH $29 MILLION
FOR DENYING PASSENGERS THE USE
OF DRINK VOUCHERS THAT DIDN'T
HAVE AN EXPIRATION DATE.
THE CLASS ACTION SUIT COVERS
5.8 MILLION UNREDEEMED TICKETS
ISSUED BEFORE AUGUST OF 2010.
THAT'S WHEN SOUTHWEST CHANGED
THE POLICY BECAUSE PEOPLE WERE
USING PHOTOCOPIES OF
VOUCHERS.
>>> 90 MILLION AMERICANS WILL
TRAVEL MORE THAN 50 MILES.
90% WILL DO SO ON THE ROAD.
SOME GOOD NEWS, GAS PRICES
CONTINUE TO FALL.
IN CALIFORNIA GAS COSTS $3.62
A GALLON.
THAT'S DOWN FROM
MID-NOVEMBER.
THE BAY AREA IS AVERAGING
$3.71 A GALLON.
THE MOST EXPENSIVE CITY?
SAN FRANCISCO AT $3.83.
VALLEJO HAS THE CHEAPEST
PRICES AT $3.49 A GALLON.
>>> IT IS NOT A CURE ALL, BUT
ONE REMEDY IS TO GIVE AND
RECEIVE A BIG HUG.
THAT'S WHAT VOLUNTEERS FROM
THE HUNTING HAPPINESS PROJECT
WERE GOING AT THE OAKLAND
FARMER'S MARKET TODAY.
THE GROUP OF GOOD SAMARITANS
WERE OFFERING NOTES OF
ENCOURAGING WORDS.
THEY SEEMED TOUCHED WITH THE
RANDOM WORDS OF KINDNESS.
>>
>> I WILL TAKE A HUG.
IT WAS ENCOURAGING.
>> I GOT TWO HUGS FROM
COMPLETE STRANGERS.
I THOUGHT IT WAS SO
HEARTWARMING CONSIDERING ALL
THAT IS GOING ON IN THE WORLD
THESE DAYS.
>> THE PROJECT OFFERS HELP TO
PEOPLE WHO NEED FOOD OR ARE
HOMELESS.
>>> SKI RESORTS IN THE SIERRA
ARE HAPPY, BUT TRAVELERS WILL
HAVE A SLIPPERY DRIVE OVER THE
NEXT SEVERAL DAYS.
THERE IS A LOT OF SNOW ON THE
GROUND ALREADY.
PLENTY FOR THE KIDS TO ENJOY
ON THE HOLIDAY BREAK.
MORE SNOWFALL IS EXPECTED
TONIGHT AND TOMORROW.
THE SNOW ELEVATION IS DOWN TO
ABOUT 2500 FEET AND IS
EXPECTED TO CONTINUE TO DROP
OVER THE NEXT FEW DAYS.
METEOROLOGIST LEIGH GLASER IS
HERE.
WE HAVE SOME MORE SYSTEMS
COMING OUR WAY.
>> ESPECIALLY AS WE HEAD
TOWARD THE LATTER PART OF THE
WORK WORKWEEK.
THE ONE TONIGHT IS WEAK IN
COMPARISON TO WHAT WE CAN
EXPECT AS WE HEAD INTO
THURSDAY AND EARLY FRIDAY.
HERE IS A LOOK FROM OUR HIGH
DEFINITION SUTRO CAM.
YOU CAN SEE REDUCED
VISIBILITY.
A BIT OF FOG DEVELOPING OVER
THE CITY AS WELL AS MIST AND
DRIZZLE.
THEY ARE ALREADY PICKING UP
LIGHT RAIN THAT IS STARTING TO
ADVANCE FROM NORTH TO SOUTH
OVER THE NORTH BAY.
WE ARE SEEING SOME RAIN RIGHT
NOW DOWN TOWARD SANTA ROSA.
WE ARE SEEING RAIN FROM
WINDSOR TO SANTA ROSA AS WELL
AND EXTENDING TO SAN RAFAEL
AND EVEN TIBURON15 TO 20
MINUTES.
AND THIS IS ACTUALLY WHERE THE
COLD FRONT IS UP ALONG THE
NORTH COAST.
CRESCENT CITY HAS BEEN GETTING
HIT WITH MODERATE RAIN IN THE
PAST HOUR OR SO HEADING
SOUTH.
YOU CAN SEE ALL OF THIS IS
MOVING FROM NORTH TO SOUTH.
IT WILL CONTINUE TO MOVE OVER
THE BAY AREA.
55 IN NAPA AND 54 IN OAKLAND
AND 56 IN SAN JOSE.
HERE IS A LOOK AT OUR
FORECAST.
WE WILL GO WITH INCREASING
RAIN OVERNIGHT.
GET READY FOR A WET MONDAY
MORNING COMMUTE AND A STORMY
OUTLOOK TOWARD THE LATTER PART
OF THE WORKWEEK.
HERE IS A LOOK AT THE OF THE
COULD.
OUR SATELLITE-RADAR COMPOSITE,
THIS IS THE LEADING EDGE --
THE LEADING EDGE WAS ABOUT
RIGHT HERE AND THIS IS THE
BACK EDGE.
th IS THE COLD AIR THAT
WILL SETTLE IN BEHIND THE COLD
FRONT.
THAT WILL BE WITH US AS WE
HEAD INTO TUESDAY AND
WEDNESDAY.
THIS IS 11:00 AND YOU WILL SEE
OVERNIGHT HOURS AND THE COLD
FRONT SLIDES SOUTH.
THE BULK OF THE RAIN OVER THE
ENTIRE BAY AREA, AND THEN LOOK
AS WE HEAD TOWARD THE NOONTIME
AREA.
IT PUSHES TOWARD THE SOUTH.
THIS IS 9:00 A.M.
ALREADY SEEING SOME PARTIAL
CLEARING IN THE NORTH BAY.
1, 2, 3, 4 AND JUST IN TIME
FOR THE 5:00 DRIVE HOME.
YOU CAN SEE SOME DRY PAVEMENT
AND MOST OF THE SHOWERS HAVE
MOVED ON OUT.
AS WE MENTIONED WINTER STORM
WARNING FOR THE SIERRA NEVADA
THROUGH MONDAY NIGHT.
CLOSE TO A FOOT OF SNOW NEAR
LAKE LEVEL.
ALREADY CHAIN CONTROLS UP ON
THE 80 AND THE 50.
KEEP THAT IN MIND.
THE LOWS TONIGHT WILL KEEP
THEM WARMER THANKS TO THE
WARMER AIR MASS THAT IS OVER
US.
40s FOR THE MOST PART ACROSS
THE BAY AREA.
AND HIGHS TOMORROW, REMEMBER
TOMORROW MORNING THAT'S WHEN
THE RAIN MOVES IN AND THEN WE
WILL PARTIAL CLEARING.
SANTA ROSA 53.
52 FOR SAN FRANCISCO.
54 FOR LIVERMORE.
56 FOR SANTA CRUZ AND GILROY.
57 DEGREES.
MY ACCU-WEATHER SEVEN-DAY
FORECAST, FOLKS GET READY FOR
A ROUGH RIDE AS WE HEAD TOWARD
THE LATTER PART OF THE WEEK.
WE WILL GO WITH THE MORNING
RAIN AND THEN AFTERNOON
CLEARING.
A CHANCE OF COLD SHOWERS HERE
AND THERE.
WEDNESDAY MORNING WE WILL LOOK
FOR SOME FROSTY STARTS FOR
MUCH OF THE BAY AREA AND THEN
THURSDAY, THICKENING CLOUDS
STORMS MOVE IN.
PERIODS OF RAIN ON SATURDAY
AND A POSSIBILITY OF ANOTHER
STORM MOVING IN ON SATURDAY
NIGHT AND SUNDAY.
>> THANK YOU, LEIGH.
>>> MIKE SHUMANN IS HERE WITH
SPORTS AND A BIG GAME FOR THE
9ER.
>> I AM EXHAUSTED JUST
WATCHING IT.
NINERS LOOK LIKE THEY WILL RUN
AWAY FROM THE PAY PATRIOTS.
BUT THEY GAVE UP 28 UNANSWERED
POINTS IN THE SECOND HALF.
WHAT A GAME, AND WE HAVE IT
NIGHT NINERS AND -- THE
THINERS AND PATRIOTS
FACE-OFF.
THE 49ERS DOMINATED THE FIRST
AND THE PATRIOTS IN THE
SECOND.
A COLD AND RAINY NIGHT IN NEW
ENGLAND.
HE GETS THE NINERS ON THE
BOARD FIRST.
24-YARD STRIKE TO FORMER PAY
PATRIOT, RANDY MOSS.
THE SECOND QUARTER AND FOUND A
CAKE IN THE POCKET AND RIGHT
ON THE MONEY TO WALKER AND
MAKES UP FOR THE FUMBLE IN THE
RED ZONE.
17-39ER TEES HALF.
THE SECOND HALF AND HE KNOCKS
THE BALL OUT OF RIDLEY'S
HANDS.
THE SECOND FUMBLE BY RIDLEY.
HE SCOOPS IT UP, GOES 66 YARDS
ALL THE WAY DOWN TO THE
PATRIOTS' FOUR-YARD LINE.
AND NOW KAEPERNICK HAD TROUBLE
WITH THE SNAP ALL NIGHT.
FOUR FUMBLES BY THE YOUNG
QUARTERBACK.
FRANK GORE SAVES THIS ONE AND
SOMEHOW SCORES ON THE PLAY.
WITH THE GLOVE ON AND
EVERYTHING HE WAS SHAKY UNDER
CENTER.
TOM BRADY AND 200
INTERCEPTIONS IN THE WHOLE
GAME.
SMITH GETS HIS FIRST CAREER
PICK.
BRADY THREW FOR 434 YARDS.
NEXT PLAY AND KAEP THE THIRD
TD OF THE GAME AND THREADING
THE NEEDLE TO CRABTREE.
WHAT A CATCH.
31-3.
GAME OVER, RIGHT?
WRONG.
BRADY TO AARON HERNANDEZ.
31-24 GAME.
BRADY GETS THE BALL BACK.
DOWN THE SIDELINE 20* LLOYD.
DOWN THE SIDELINE TO LLOYD.
A FEW PLAYS LATER.
HE TIES THE GAME.
ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
HE RETURNS THE ENSUING
KICKOFF.
TO CRABTREE AGAIN.
SEVEN COULD -- SEVEN CATCHES
FOR MICHAEL AND THEY IMPROVED
TO 10-3-1.
THEY CLINCHED A WILD CARD SPOT
IN THE PLAYOFFS.
>> WE KNEW WE WERE GOING TO
HAVE TO PUT UP POINTS.
TOM BRADY AND THE OFFENSE CAN
PUT UP A LOT OF POINTS.
WE KNEW WE WERE GOING TO MATCH
THAT.
>> THEY WERE A VERY GOOD TEAM
AND A VERY GOOD DEFENSE.
THEY PLAY HARD.
WE SPOTTED THEM 28 POINTS.
YOU CAN'T PLAY POORLY AGAINST
A GOOD TEAM AND EXPECT TO
WIN.
>> WE CAN WIN A SHOOTOUT.
WHATEVER IT TAKES.
THAT'S OUR MOTTO.
>> UP NORTH, THE SEAHAWKS
KEEPING PRESSURE ON BEATING
THE BILLS.
WHAT A YEAR HE IS HAVING.
THE DEFENSE K5EU78 L -- CAME
UP BIG.
HE GOES 57 YARDS THE OTHER
WAY.
THEY FACE THE SEAHAWKS NEXT
SUNDAY IN SEATTLE.
THEY CAN CLINCH WITH A WIN.
A LOSS AND IT COMES DOWN TO
THE FINAL WEEKEND OF THE
SEASON.
WE WILL TAKE A BRIEF TIMEOUT
BEFORE WE JUMP OVER TO THE
AFC.
THEY ENDED A SIX-GAME LOSING
STREAK BEATING KANSAS CITY.
THEI
>>> THE RAIDERS ARE PLAYING
THEIR FINAL HOME GAME.
THEY BEAT KANSAS CITY, THE
LAST TEAM THEY BEAT SEVEN
WEEKS AGO.
THEY IMPROVED TO 4 AND 10.
TWO OF THE FOUR WINS ARE
AGAINST THE CHIEFS.
THIS YOUNG RAIDER FAN OFFERING
HER PRAYERS TO THE VICTIMS OF
NEWTOWN.
THIRD QUARTER AND DARRIN
McFADEN BUSTS LOOSE FOR 110
YARDS.
HIS LONGEST, THIS 19-YARDER.
JANIKOWSKI'S FOURTH FIELD GOAL
OF THE GAME.
12-0 RAIDERS.
THE RAIDERS DEFENSE SHUT OUT
THE CHIEFS.
FIRST SHUTOUT SINCE 2002.
HIS FIRST SACK OF THE SEASON
WENT TO A RAIDER'S GAME AND A
SOCCER MATCH BROKE OUT.
15-0 YOUR FINAL.
>> I THINK OUR GUYS NEEDED
SOMETHING WHERE THEY GET A
LITTLE CONFIDENCE.
I THOUGHT THEY HAD A GREAT
WEEK OF PRACTICE.
I THOUGHT THEY WERE FOCUSED IN
ON WHAT WEED -- WHAT WE NEEDED
TO DO, AND I THOUGHT THEY DID
A GREAT JOB EXECUTING THEM
TODAY.
>> OUR DEFENSE OUT PLAYED
THEM.
IT IS GOOD TO GET A WIN VERSUS
A TEAM THAT WAS STRUGGLING AND
COMING IN HERE.
IT HAS HAD A LOT OF SUCCESS.
>> IT FEELS BETTER WHEN YOU
WIN.
DENVER HAS THE AFC LOCKED UP.
MADE A STATEMENT IN
BALTIMORE.
HE PICKS OFF JOE FLACO AND
GOES 98 YARDS THE OTHER WAY.
THE AFC ARE THE SECOND SEED
WITH THE PATRIOTS' LOSS.
34-17 THAT FINAL.
THIS ABC7 SPORTS REPORT
BROUGHT TO YOU BY RIVER ROCK
CASINO.
WE WILL TAKE A TOUR AROUND THE
LEAGUE WITH THE PLAYS OF THE
DAY, AND MORE FROM THE 49ERS
LATER IN THIS NEWSCAST.
STICK AROUND.
>>> STILL TO COME, THE GUN
DEBATE, AND WHY DESPITE THE
PRY TO GET THEM OFF THE
STREETS.
AND HOW RESIDENTS ARE HONORING
THE VICTIM OF THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
AND THE DRUG TRIAL THAT COULD
PUT TARGETED CANCER DRUGS TO
WORK ON PATIENTS IN THE NEAR
FUTURE.
THE BAY AREA RESEARCHERS DOING
THE WORK.
WE WILL BE RIGHT BACK.
>>> I'M AMA DATES.
234 TONIGHT'S HEADLINES,
DEVELOP ARE NEWS HIGHWAY 121
IS CLOSED THIS BOTH DIRECTIONS
BETWEEN STONE CREST DRIVE 1K3
HAGIN ROAD.
IT WAS CAUSED BY AN ACCIDENT
THAT KNOCKED DOWN POWER
LINES.
IT IS EXPECTED TO REOPEN AT
7:00 IN THE MORNING.
>>> THE NAME OF THE CHP
OFFICER KILLED HAS BEEN
RELEASED.
JOHN FENIN DIED WHEN HE FELL
OFF HIS MOTORCYCLE AND WAS HIT
BY ANOTHER CAR.
>>> A CAR FIRE ON HIGHWAY 24
FORCED THE CLOSURE OF AN
EXIT.
THE DRIVER LOST CONTROL AND
THE CAR OVERTURNED.
THE DRIVER AND PASSENGER GOT
OUT SAFELY.
>>> A PEDESTRIAN WAS KILLED
AFTER BEING HIT BY A TRAIN IN
UNINCORPORATED HAYWARD.
THE TRACKS WERE CLOSED WHILE
AUTHORITIES INVESTIGATED.
>>> THE MASACRE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IS ONE OF
THE MANY OF THE MASS
SHOOTINGS.
IN EACH ONE THERE IS A CLOSER
LOOK AT THE GUNS USED IN THE
ATTACK.
SENATOR FEINSTEIN WILL CALL ON
A VOTE THE FIRST DAY CONGRESS
IS BACK IN SESSION.
>> IT WILL BAN THE SALE, THE
TRANSFER, THE IMPORTATION AND
THE POSSESSION.
NOT RETROACTIVELY, BUT
PERSPECTIVELY.
IT WILL BAN THE SAME FOR BIG
CLIPS, DRUMS OR STRIPS OF MORE
THAN 10 BULLETS.
>> DESPITE TRYING TO GET GUNS
OFF THE STREETS THE NUMBER
CONTINUES TO SORE.
>> ON BLACK FRIDAY U.S.
SHOPPERS WERE THOUGHT JUST
BUYING TOYS AND ELECTRONICS,
BUT THEY WERE ALSO BUYING GUNS
IN RECORD NUMBERS OF THE ON
THAT SINGLE DAY THEY DID
COMPUTERIZED BACKGROUND CHECKS
ON MORE THAN 154,000 PURCHASES
OF FIRE ARLS.
AND IN NOVEMBER ALONE,
AMERICANS TRIED TO BUY A
WHOOPING TWO MILLION GUNS.
HERE ARE SOME FACTS THAT MIGHT
SURPRISE YOU.
THERE ARE MORE REGISTERED GUN
DEALERS THAN SUPERMARKETS.
MORE GUN SELLERS THAN
McDONALDS RESTAURANTS.
THE OVER -- OVERWHELMINGMENT A
ARE LAW ABIDING CITIZENS.
DISTURBED PEOPLE WILL OFTEN BE
ABLE TO OBTAIN THEM.
EVEN IN QUIET COMMUNITIES LIKE
NEWTOWN.
WE SPOKE TO THE ATF
COMMANDER.
>> ROUGHLY HOW MANY GUN
DEALERS ARE IN THIS AREA.
>> THERE ARE ROUGHLY 400 GUN
DEALERS IN THE AREA.
JUST WITHIN 10 MILES THERE ARE
36 GUN DEALERS.
>> THEY BELIEVE THE GUNS USED
ON THE KILLING SPREE WERE
BOUGHT LEGALLY.
>> IN AMERICA UNLESS YOU HAVE
A FELONY CONVICTION OR YOU ARE
ADJUDICATED TO BE MENTALLY
INCOME TENT YOU HAVE READY
ACCESS TO FIREARMS.
>> LANZA JOINS THE RANKS OF
OTHER MASS SHOOTERS.
THE NATION IS LEFT WITH A
VEXING QUESTION.
HOW DO YOU KEEP WEAPONS FROM
MEN LIKE THESE WHEN THERE IS
AN ESTIMATED 200 MILLION PLUS
GUNS ALREADY IN CIRCULATION?
>> ABC NEWS IS DEVOTING NEXT
WEEK TO COVERAGE OF THE
TRAGEDY "THE SEARCH FOR
SOLUTIONS" STARTS TOMORROW
MORNING FROM 7:00 TO 9:00.
FOR THE LATEST TUNE INTO THE
ABC7 MORNING NEWS AT 4:30
A.M.
>>> HERE IN THE BAY AREA, MANY
ARE TURNING TO THEIR CHURCHES
FOR SOLACE.
THOMAS ROMAN HAS THE STORY.
>> AT MORNING MASS AT SAINT
MARY'S COULD YOU THEY'D RAIL
IN -- CATHEDRAL THIS WAS
WRITTEN FOR THE VICTIMS.
HE HAD PRAYERS ALREADY
PLANNED.
>> TODAY IS A DAY TO PRAY,
ESPECIALLY FOR ALL OF THOSE
PEOPLE THAT WERE MASACRED AND
FOR THEIR FAMILIES.
>> A GREAT VIOLENCE HAS BE
FALLEN US AGAIN.
>> HE IS THE PASTOR OF SAINT
MARY'S PEOPLE HAVE COME TO
MASS NOT JUST TO PRAY, BUT TO
TRY AND MAKE SOME SENSE OF THE
EVIL THAT OCCURRED.
>> SEEKING TO FIND CONSULATION
IN THE PROMISE AND THE HOPE OF
A GOD WHO FEELS WITH US AND
LONGS TO HELP US.
>> THE CHURCH DID WHAT IT DOES
BEST.
THEY HELP CELEBRATE LIFE WHILE
RECOVERING FROM THE TRAGEDY.
THE CHURCH WAS FILLED TO
STANDING ROOM ONLY.
HE SAYS THE RESPONSE IS
INCREDIBLE.
>> I HAVE NEVER SEEN IT
TOUCHED LIKE THIS.
IF NIFT YEARS I NEVER SEEN --
IN 50 YEARS I NEVER SEEN IT
TOUCHED COMMUNITIES AND
INDIVIDUALS LIKE THIS.
>> THE KILLING OF INNOCENTS
HAS AFFECTED PEOPLE
EVERYWHERE.
>> IT HAPPENS ALL OVER THE
WORLD.
HE WENT FOR THE CHILDREN.
HE WENT TO DESTROY THE
CHILDREN FOR SOME REASON.
>> MANY OF THE PEOPLE WHO CAME
WITH THEIR CHILDREN HELD THEM
TIGHT.
THIS IS KIERNAN'S FIRST VISIT
AND SHE BROUGHT HER DAUGHTER
KATIE FOR SPIRITUAL HEALING.
>> THIS IS HER FIRST TIME
HERE.
JUST SO SHARE THE LOVE AND I
THINK THE HEARTACHE THAT
EVERYBODY IS FEELING.
TREMENDOUS HEARTACHE.
>> BECAUSE OF THE HEARTACHE,
THE BURLINGAME COMMUNITY WILL
HOLD A SPECIAL PRAYER SERVICE
AT 7:00 P.M.
IT WILL BE HELD AT THE FIRST
PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH IN
BURLINGAME.
ABC7 NEWS.
>> YOU CAN EXPRESS YOUR
SYMPATHY BY POSTING THIS BADGE
TO YOUR FACEBOOK WALL.
A SILENT SHOW OF SUPPORT FOR
EVERYONE IN CONNECTICUT.
>>> A GROUP ANONYMOUS IS
RENEWING THEIR SUPPORT AFTER
THE ORGANIZATION PRAISED THE
ACTIONS OF THE SHOOTER IN THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL MASACRE.
THE KANSAS-BASED CHURCH SAYS
IT WILL CLAIM GOD'S WILL IS
PUNISHING AMERICA FOR
SUPPORTING GAY MARRIAGE.
ANONYMOUS STARTED IT BY
POSTING DETAILED PERSONAL
INFORMATION ABOUT ALL CHURCH
MEMBERS ON-LINE.
>>> STILL TO COME, A NEW DRUG
TRIAL COULD MAKE A BIG
DIFFERENCE FOR BREAST CANCER
PATIENTS.
AND IT IS HAPPENING IN THE BAY
AREA.
>> AND A RETURN TO MIDDLE
EARTH.
JUST AHEAD, HOW THE HOBBIT
STEPPED UP TO THE LORD OF THE
RINGS TRILOGY.
>> AND WE WILL ALSO CHECK IN
WITH LIVE DOPPLER 7HD.
WE ARE CHECKING ON THE
SHOWERS.
WHAT WILL THAT MEAN FOR YOUR
>>> AN INNOVATIVE DRUG TRIAL
IN THE BAY AREA COULD PUT
TARGETED CANCER DRUGS TO WORK
ON PATIENTS IN THE VERY NEAR
FUTURE.
THE EFFORT IS BEING
ACCELERATED BY A NEW
UNDERSTANDING OF THE DISEASE
ITSELF.
ABC NEWS REPORTER CAROLYN
JOHNSON HAS THE DOOY TAILS.
>> AS A BREAST CANCER SURVIVOR
AND ADVOCATE SHE NEVER STOPPED
LEARNING ABOUT HER ENEMY.
A CONSORTIUM RELEASED RESULTS
FROM A GENOME STUDY.
IT HELPED TO REDEFINE SUBTYPES
OF BREAST CANCER BASED ON
MOLECULAR MAKE UP AS OPPOSED
TO WHERE THEY APPEAR ON THE
BODY.
>> THAT'S A BIG DEAL.
I WENT AND SAW MY DOCTOR AND
SAID WHICH SUBTYPE AM I?
I WANTED THAT INFORMATION.
>> LOUIS SUFFERED FROM TRIPLE
NEGATIVE WHICH REFERS TO THE
LACK OF PROTEIN RECEPTORS
FOUND IN OTHER VARIETIES.
DOCTORS BELIEVE TRIPLE
NEGATIVE BREAST CANCER MAY
HAVE MONTH ARE IN COMMON WITH
OVARIAN CANCER.
>> EXCITING BECAUSE
RESEARCHERS BELIEVE THEY ARE
CLOSER TO USING GENE TESTING
AND BIO MARKERS TO MATCH
CANCER PATIENTS WITH THE
EMERGING DRUGS.
>> IT IS NOT OH ONE KIND OF
BREAST CANCER.
EACH OF THESE ARE FAIRLY
DIFFERENT KINDS OF DISEASE.
YOU HAVE TO TEST DRUGS FOR HOW
THEY MIGHT BEHAVE IN EACH ONE
OF THE TUMOR SUBSETS.
>> SHE HELPS WITH A TRIAL THAT
AIMES TO DEVELOP THAT SORT OF
PRECISION DIAGNOSIS AND
TREATMENT.
IN THE TRIAL, PATIENTS ARE
GRIFFIN DRUGS WELL BEFORE THEY
ARE REMOVED.
THAT GIVES THEM TIME TO
EVALUATE THE DRUG'S
EFFECTIVENESS AGAINST A
VARIETY OF CANCER TYPES.
RESULTS ON NEARLY HALF A DOZEN
EXPERIMENTAL DRUGS WITH
EXPECTED IN A MATTER OF
MONTHS.
THEY BELIEVE THE PACE OF NEW
TREATMENTS WILL ACCELERATE.
>> I THINK WE WILL HAVE MUCH
BETTER TREATMENTS USING
COMBINATION OF AGENTS FOR THE
POSITIVE BREAST CANCERS.
THOSE WILL HAVE GONE FROM THE
MOSTLY THAT WILL TO THE LEAST
LETHAL.
I THINK WE WILL HAVE IN NEW
AGENTS FOR TRIPLE NEGATIVE
CANCER.
>> SHE IS BUSY RAISING HER
THREE CHILDREN AND RUNNING A
SUPPORT 2K3WR0U7 CALLED TRIPLE
STEP TOWARD A TOUR.
DOCTORS WORK TOWARD MORE
TARGETED AND MORE EFFECTIVE
TREATMENTS.
>> YES TO HAVE A VERY TARGETED
DRUG FOR EACH PATIENT WOULD BE
IDEAL.
>> CAROLYN JOHNSON, ABC7
NEWS.
>> I SPY IS AN ON GOING
TRIAL.
WE HAVE MORE INFORMATION ON
THE STUDY AND THE ORGANIZATION
TRIPLE STEP TOWARD THE CURE ON
ABC7NEWS.COM.
>>> MIDDLE EARTH IS BACK ON
TOP OF THE BOX OFFICE.
PETER JACKSON'S "THE HOBBIT"
TOOK IN $285 MILLION.
IT WAS STRONGER THAN THE THREE
PREVIOUS "LORD OF THE RINGS"
FILMS.
AND "RISE OF THE GUARDIANS"
PULLED IN THE FAMILY CROWD.
AND "LINCOLN" EARNED ANOTHER
$7 MILLION OVER THE WEEKEND"
SKY FALL IS STILL HANGING ON
AT NUMBER FOUR.
AND "LIFE OF PI" WRAPS UP THIS
WEEKEND'S TOP FIVE FILMS.
>>> AND LEIGH GLASER SAYS
TOMORROW IS A GOOD DAY TO TAKE
IN A MOVIE.
HOW MUCH RAIN WILL WE GET?
>> A QUARTER INCH IN MOST
LOCATIONS.
LIVE DOPPLER 7HD IS STARTING
TO SEE THE SHOWERS, THE BANDS
OF RAIN PICKING UP IN THE
NORTH BAY.
IT IS HEADING DOWN TOWARD
SANTA ROSA AND EVEN FAIRFAX.
SAN FRANCISCO NEAR THE GOLDEN
GATE BRIDGE AS WELL IS PICKING
UP SOME RAIN.
OVERNIGHT AS YOU SLEEP MOST OF
THE RAIN WILL MOVE THROUGH.
THIS IS YOUR 5:00 A.M. COMMUTE
HOUR.
YOU CAN SEE WET PAVEMENT.
THE RAIN WILL PERSIST ACROSS
THE BAY AREA.
AS WE GET INTO THE LUNCHTIME
HOUR, THAT'S 9:00 A.M.
THE LUNCHTIME HOUR, ONE, TWO,
THREE, THE RAIN MOVES ON
TOWARD THE SOUTH, AND WE WILL
ACTUALLY SEE SOME PARTIAL
CLEARING BY LATE TOMORROW
AFTERNOON.
24 IS YOUR 5:00 DRIVE HOME.
MAYBE DRY PAVEMENT FOR YOU
THERE.
IT WILL BE WET ON THE EAST
COAST.
65 ATLANTA AND 56 WASHINGTON,
D.C.
NEW YORK SCATTERED SHORT AND
49.
WE WILL LOOK FOR CLEAR
CONDITIONS.
SALT LAKE CITY WILL SEE SOME
SNOW.
THE HIGHER ELEVATIONS THERE.
DENVER THE HIGHER ELEVATIONS.
53 IN SEATTLE AND MORE RAIN
THERE.
TOMORROW AFTERNOON A
TEMPERATURE OF 41.
IF YOU ARE TRAVELING INTO
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA, WE WILL
LOOK FOR SOME SHOWERS.
LOS ANGELES 63 AND 64 FOR SAN
DIEGO.
SNOW AND WINTER STORM WARNING
FOR THE LAKE TAHOE AREA.
AROUND 40 DEGREES THERE AND
LOOK FOR 57 AND SHOWERS FOR
SACRAMENTO.
MY ACCU-WEATHER SEVEN-DAY
FORECAST A FEW SHOWERS ON
TUESDAY WITH FROST.
AND THEN A SERIES OF STORMS
BEGIN ON THURSDAY.
RAIN AND GUSTY WINDS AND HEAVY
RAIN AT TIMES.
FRIDAY PERIODS OF RAIN AND
THEN ANOTHER STORM IS DUE IN
HERE ON SATURDAY.
OF COURSE, MIKE NIKO WILL BE
HERE WITH AN UPDATE 4:30 TO
7:00 A.M.
>> SOUNDS GOOD.
THANK YOU, LEIGH.
>>> SHU IS HERE WITH SPORTS.
AND DARE I SAY IT WAS A GREAT
DAY FOR THE TEAMS?
>> FIRST TIME IN AWHILE THE
49ERS AND THE RAIDERS ARE ON
THE WINNING SLATE.
HIGHLIGHTS AND REACTIONS.
>> AND WE WILL TAKE YOU TO OUR
COMBOS AND PLAYS OF THE DAY.
>>> GAME OF THE DAY IN THE
NFL.
49ERS AND PATRIOTS IN NEW
ENGLAND.
TWO DIFFERENT HALVES.
49ERS DOMINATED THE FIRST
WHILE TOM BRADY ROARED BACK
WITH 29 UNANSWERED POINTS.
IF YOU LIKE ROLLERCOASTERS,
HERE WE GO.
A COLD AND RAINY NIGHT.
STORM FRONT COMING IN.
KAEPERNICK STRIKES FIRST AND
7-049ERS.
SECOND QUARTER AND ON THE
MONEY TO WALKER.
HE MAKES UP FOR A FUMBLE IN
THE RED ZONE EARLIER.
34-YARD STRIKE.
LET'S GO TO THE THIRD
QUARTER.
HIS THIRD TD PASS OF THE
GAME.
THREADS THE NEEDLE AND 27
YARDS AND 31-349ERS.
GAME IS OVER, RIGHT?
>> HUH-UH.
28 UNANSWERED BY THE
PATRIOTS.
DOWN THE SIDELINES AND HE HAD
10 CATCHES.
190 YARDS FOR THE FORMER 9ER.
WE HAVE A TIE TBAIM.
TIE GAME.
AFTER THEY RETURNED THE
ENSUING KICKOFF AND THE NEXT
PLAY AND FOUR TD PASSES TO
CRABTREE.
216 YARDS AND SEVEN CATCHES
AND 107 YARDS AND TWO TD'S.
THEY ADD A LATE FIELD GOAL.
THEY CLINCH A WILD CARD SPOT.
>> A GREAT VICTORY.
I REALLY LOVE HOW THE TEAM
SUCKED IT UP.
WE DIDN'T MAKE ALL OF THE
PLAYS.
WE MADE A LOT OF PLAYS.
>> THEY WERE GOING TO MAKE
THEIR PLAYS.
WE PUT IT TO THEM IN THE FIRST
HALF.
>> AND DEFENSE WE KNOW WE NEED
A COUPLE MORE STOPS AND THAT'S
WHAT WE DID.
>> AROUND THE NFC, SEATTLE
KEEPING THE PRESSURE ON THE
9ERS AND BEATING THE BILLS.
HE RAN FOR THREE TOUCH DOWNS.
WHAT A YEAR THIS ROOKIE IS
HAVING.
DEFENSE CAME UP BIG.
HE GOES 57 YARDS THE OTHER
WAY.
50-17 THE FINAL.
A WIN AND THEY CLINCH THE NFC
WEST.
A LOSS AND IT GOES DOWN TO THE
FINAL WEEKEND.
FALCONS HAVE THE TOP SEED IN
THE NFC AND SHOWED WHY AGAINST
THE GIANTS.
TO TONY GONZALEZ AND 14-0
ATLANTA AFTER ONE QUARTER.
RYAN COULD DO NO WRONG.
270 YARDS TD'S AND TWO TO
JULIO JONES.
FALCONS DOWN AT HOME AND HANG
ON TO THE TOP SPOT IN THE
NFC.
A 34-0 SHUTOUT OF THE GIANTS.
TIGERS AND BEARS.
WHAT A GAME FOR JAMES JONES.
FIVE RECEPTIONS AND GREEN BAY
CLINCHES THE NFC NORTH FOR THE
SECTD SEASON WITH A 21-13
VICTORY AND ARE A THIRD SEED
IN THE NFC WITH THE 49ER I CAN
HAVE TORY.
STAR OF THE DAY, ADRIAN
PETERSON.
212 YARDS RUSHING AND ONE
TOUCHDOWN.
HE IS 200 YARDS SHY OF THE ALL
TIME LEADINGS IN A SEASON.
VIKINGS WIN IT 36-22 THE
FINAL.
THE RAIDERS FINALLY END THEIR
SIX-GAME SLIDE IN A HOME
GAME.
THEY BEAT KANSAS CITY AND TWO
OF THEIR FOUR WINS ARE AGAINST
THE CHIEFS.
THIS YOUNG RAIDER FAN IS
OFFERING PRAYERS FOR THE
VICTIMS OF NEWTOWN.
HE RAD FOR 110 YARDS AND ON 30
CARRIES AND FINALLY BUSTED
OUT.
THAT LEADS TO JANIKOWSKI'S
FOURTH FIELD GOAL.
RAIDERS' DEFENSE SHUT ON THE
THE CHIEFS.
THE FIRST ONE SINCE 2002 FOR
THE SILVER AND BLACK.
RAIDERS SNAP THE SKID BEHIND
JANIKOWSKI'S FIVE FIELD
GOALS.
>> I THINK OUR GUYS NEEDED
SOMETHING WHERE THEY GET A
LITTLE CONFIDENCE.
I THOUGHT THEY HAD A GREAT
WEEK OF PRACTICE.
I THOUGHT THEY WERE FOCUSED ON
WHAT WOO WE NEEDED TO DO AND
HOW DO WE WIN THIS GAME.
THEY DID A GREAT JOB.
>> OUR DEFENSE OUT PLAYED
THEM.
IT IS GOOD TO GET A WIN VERSUS
A TEAM THAT WAS STRUGGLING.
COMING IN HERE, IT HAS HAD A
LOT OF SUCCESS.
>> AROUND THE AFC, ANDREW LUCK
AGAINST THE TOP SEEDED
TEXANS.
HE SCOOPS AND SCORES AND
23-TEXANS.
ANDREW THREW FOR TWO
TOUCHDOWNS INCLUDING THIS
61-YARDER, BUT IT WASN'T
ENOUGH.
A 29-17 VICTORY.
DENVER LOCKED UP THE AFC
WEST.
THEY MADE A STATEMENT THOUGH.
IT IS A LONG WAY.
HE DID MAKE IT TO THE END
ZONE.
PEYTON MANNING MEANWHILE LEIGH
GLASER'S FAVORITE THREW ONE TD
PASS.
A 51-YARD STRIKE TO DECKER.
BRONCOS WITH A 9-GAME WIN
STREET.
THEY TAKE OVER THE SECOND
PLACE WITH THE PATRIOTS LOSS.
THIS SPORTS REPORT IS BROUGHT
TO YOU BY RIVER ROCK CASINO.
WHAT A DAY IN THE NFL.
A GREAT WIN FOR THE 40
THINERS.
NOW THEY HAVE TO KEEP IT
GOING.
>> THANK YOU, SHU.
AND THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
THE ABC7 NEWS.
WE CONTINUE TOMORROW MORNING
AT 4:30.
FOR LEIGH GLASER AND MIKE
SHUMANN AND ALL OF US HERE AT
ABC, THANK YOU FOR JOINING US
AND HAVE A GREAT NIGHT.
AND...
TAKE CARE OF THEM,
YOU KNOW?
I FEEL LIKE WE'VE
COME FULL CIRCLE.
LIKE THAT!
THIS IS HOW
I'LL DO IT.
Sarah:
THERE YOU GO.
THERE ARE TWO KINDS OF FOLKS
WHO SIT AROUND THINKING ABOUT
HOW TO KILL PEOPLE--PSYCHOPATHS
AND MYSTERY WRITERS.
I'M THE KIND THAT PAYS BETTER.
WHO AM I?
I'M RICK CASTLE.
CASTLE.
I REALLY AM
RUGGEDLY HANDSOME, AREN'T I?
EVERY WRITER
NEEDS INSPIRATION,