WEEK.
ALL THAT, "HOT TOPICS" AND MORE
COMING UP ON "THE VIEW."
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> SO HELLO AND WELCOME TO "THE
VIEW."
YOU KNOW, THE ENTIRE COUNTRY IS
BEYOND HEARTBROKEN AFTER THIS
TRAGIC MASSACRE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AND THAT IS JUST
ALMOST TOO AWFUL TO COMPREHEND.
I CAN'T IMAGINE WITH YOU GUYS
WITH THE KIDS, WITH LITTLE ONES,
HOW YOU -- HOW YOU'RE TALKING
ABOUT IT OR ARE YOU TALKING
ABOUT IT.
>> WE WERE TEXTING BACK AND
FORTH ABOUT IT.
WHAT DID YOU END UP DOING WITH
JEFFREY?
>> WELL, THE PRINCIPAL AT
JEFFREY'S SCHOOL SENT US AN
E-MAIL AND SAID BECAUSE IT'S SO
YOUNG KEEP THE TVs OFF AND
SHIELD THEM AS MUCH AS POSSIBLE.
IF THEY WERE UNAWARE THEN IT WAS
UP TO US AND I FELT FOR JEFFREY,
HE WAS NOT AWARE OF WHAT WAS
GOING ON AND I CHOSE NOT TO PUT
MY ISSUES ON HIM SO I CHOSE NOT
TO TELL JEFFREY ANYTHING.
>> BUT HE MIGHT HEAR ABOUT IT,
THOUGH.
>> WE KEPT THE TV OFF BUT HE
HEARD ABOUT IT ONE TIME WHEN HE
WAS WATCHING THE KNICKS GAME AND
GAVE A MOMENT OF SILENCE FOR THE
SANDY HOOK VICTIMS AND HE SAID,
MOM
MOMMY, I THOUGHT SANDY WAS OVER.
>> HOW ABOUT YOU?
>> LIKE YOU SAID, I THINK
EVERYONE WAS IN A REALLY SAD
PLACE OF GRIEVING.
IT'S HARD.
AS A PARENT YOU NEED TO BE
STRONG FOR YOUR KIDS.
WE HAD A GOOD FRIEND TELL US
WHEN HIS DAUGHTER WAS TALKING
ABOUT COLUMBINE SHE WAS ASKING
DETAILS.
HE SAID, HONEY, WHEN WE TRAVEL
THROUGH THE AIRPORT DO I ASK YOU
TO CARRY THE HEAVIEST BAG AND
SHE SAID, NO.
HE SAID, I DON'T ASK YOU TO
CARRY THE HEAVIEST BAG BECAUSE
THAT'S MY JOB AS YOUR FATHER.
I'LL TAKE THE HEAVIEST AND YOU
TAKE THE ONE YOU CAN HANDLE.
I WENT WITH THAT.
EVERY CHILD IS DIFFERENT.
WE'RE NOT TRAINED WHAT TO DO IN
THIS SITUATION AND I TRIED TO
GIVE GRACE ONE MORE DAY OF NOT
KNOWING.
I THOUGHT SHE'D FIND OUT FROM US
OR SOMEBODY ELSE.
SOMETIMES THEY GET INFORMATION
BEFORE YOU DO AND A FRIEND DID
TELL HER DETAILED INFORMATION, A
FRIEND OF HERS TOLD HER DETAILED
INFORMATION THAT WOULD NOT HAVE
BEEN THE AMOUNT OF INFORMATION I
WOULD HAVE GIVEN HER,
NONETHELESS, I THINK WE HAD A
SOULFUL DISCUSSION ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED.
>> WHAT DID YOU TELL HER?
>> SHE WAS VERY SAD.
I MEAN VERY SAD.
>> DID YOU TELL HER THERE WAS A
BAD MAN?
HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN TO A CHILD
THIS KIND OF EVIL ESPECIALLY
WHEN I WAS LOOKING AT THE LIST
OF CHILDREN, ONE OF THE CHILDREN
WAS NAMED GRACE AND I THOUGHT,
WHAT IS ELISABETH GOING TO SAY.
>> YOU KNOW, WELL, FIRST OF ALL
CHRIS CUOMO WHO IS HERE TODAY
THANKFULLY AND I HAD A GREAT
DISCUSSION AND HE SAID, LOOK,
WE'RE OKAY, SO YOU CAN'T GET
HEAVY LIKE YOU WOULD IF IT WERE
YOUR DIRECT SITUATION, BUT I
THINK THAT, YOU KNOW, I TOLD
HER, LOOK, THIS WAS WAS A MAN
WITH A SICK MIND AND A SICK
HEART AND HE DID AN EVIL THING,
VERY EVIL THING.
IT'S OVER.
HE'S GONE.
YOU'RE SAFE.
YOU CAN -- TWO THINGS I WOULD
ASK, THOUGH BECAUSE I THINK KIDS
HAVE DIFFERENT LEVELS OF
INFORMATION.
AS I SAID GRACE IS PRIVY TO SOME
THAT I DON'T THINK WAS
APPROPRIATE FOR HER MIND AND
HEART.
ONE IF YOU'RE TALKING TO THEM
ABOUT IT, TELL THEM IT'S FAMILY
TALK OR IF THEY WANT TO TALK TO
YOU THEY CAN TALK TO YOU OR
FAMILY OR TEACHERS.
IT'S NOT RECESS TALK AND THEY
HAVE THE OPTION TO SAY IF IT
COMES UP IN THOSE SOCIAL AREAS
AND DON'T WANT TO TALK ABOUT IT
THEY CAN SAY CAN WE CHANGE THE
SUBJECT?
LET THEM HAVE A LITTLE
CONTROVERSY OVER WHAT'S IN THEIR
MIND.
>> GO YOU GO AHEAD.
>> THERE WAS A THING ON THE
INTERNET THAT MR. ROGERS WHEN HE
WAS AROUND SAID TO CHILDREN,
WHEN THINGS ARE BAD FIND THE
HELPERS.
>> YES, WE TALKED ABOUT THAT.
>> I THOUGHT THAT WAS VERY GOOD
ADVICE.
THE ADULTS NEED TO FIND
SOLUTIONS AND THE CHILDREN NEED
TO FIND HELPERS.
>> ONCE OF THE THINGS LAST
NIGHT, ONE OF THE PERSONS --
OBAMA CAME TO THE SERVICES IN
NEWTOWN, AND HE HAS BEEN -- FROM
THE TILE THIS HAPPENED HE HAS
BEEN ONE OF THE HELPERS AND
CONSOLERS BUT THEY HAD ALL OF
THE DIFFERENT AND ROGGE US
LEADERS, THE RABBIS AND MUSLIMS
AND PROSS STANTES AND SO FORTH.
EACH OF THEM FROM THAT TOWN,
EACH OF THEM SO I THOUGHT
SPECIAL AND ARTICULATE AND IT
WAS AN OPPORTUNITY NO MATTER
WHAT YOUR RELIGION TO SEE HOW
EACH OF THEM HANDLED IT AND HOW
EACH OF THEM GAVE SOLACE.
I THOUGHT THEY WERE REMARKABLE
AND IT WAS A VERY IMPORTANT PART
OF BRINGING EVERYONE TOGETHER TO
SEE THAT IT AFFECTED EVERYONE.
>> TIMES WHEN RELIGION HAS A
PART IN EVERYBODY'S LIFE WHETHER
YOU'RE AN ATHEIST OR NOT JUST
BECAUSE THERE ARE NO ANSWERS TO
THESE KIND OF QUESTIONS AND IT'S
THE ONE THING YOU CAN -- THEY'RE
SAYING, SHE'S IN HEAVEN.
SHE'S IN A BETTER PLACE AND ALL
THAT, MAYBE THAT'S THE
CONSOLATION.
>> THAT'S WHAT I GO TO.
>> THE THING THAT YOU HAVE TO DO
WITH KIDS IS JUST MY THOUGHT IS
YOU JUST HAVE TO SAY, YOU KNOW,
THIS ISN'T SOMETHING THAT I CAN
EXPLAIN TO YOU RIGHT NOW AND I
NEED SOME MORE TIME TO THINK
ABOUT IT AND WHEN I THINK I CAN
TELL YOU, THEN WE CAN SIT DOWN.
>> EACH PARENT HAS THEIR OWN WAY
OF DEALING WITH THEIR CHILDREN.
>> SO PRESIDENT OBAMA WAS IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, YESTERDAY
AS BARBARA SAID TO LEND HIS
SUPPORT TO THE GRIEVING FAMILIES
AND TOWNSPEOPLE.
TAKE A LOOK.
>> WE GATHER HERE IN MEMORY OF
20 BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN AND 6
REMARKABLE ADULTS.
AS A COMMUNITY YOU'VE INSPIRED
US, NEWTOWN.
IN THE FACE OF INDESCRIBABLE
VIOLENCE, IN THE FACE OF
UNCONSCIONABLE EVIL, YOU'VE
LOOKED OUT FOR EACH OTHER AND
YOU'VE CARED FOR ONE ANOTHER.
AND YOU HAVE A LOVED ONE
ANOTHER.
THIS IS HOW NEWTOWN WILL BE
REMEMBERED AND WITH TIME AND
GOD'S GRACE, THAT LOVE WILL SEE
YOU THROUGH.
>> THAT WAS COMFORTING.
>> AMAZING.
I MEAN --
>> ONE OF THE MOST TOUCHING
PARTS OF WHEN HE WAS TALKING WAS
WHEN HE JUST READ THE NAMES OFF
AND, YOU KNOW --
>> ALSO WHEN HE SPOKE -- WHEN HE
SPOKE THE DAY IT HAPPENED AND
YOU SAW HIM WIPE THE TEAR HE GOT
SO EMOTIONAL BECAUSE AS A PARENT
IT WAS VERY HUMAN --
>> TWO OF HIS OWN.
>> I THINK AS PRESIDENT HE SEES
THE CHILDREN OF THE COUNTRY AS
HIS CHILDREN IN A WAY, THAT
HE -- YOU KNOW --
>> I DON'T KNOW IF YOU SAW THAT
PICTURE.
A PICTURE OF HIM WITH ALL THE
KIDS CLIMBING OVER HIS KNEES BUT
ONE THING I DID I HAVE TO SAY A
THANK YOU, I WENT TO SEE CHRIS
TUCKER THAT NIGHT AND BONE
HAMPTON WENT UP AND DID STAND-UP
COMEDY AND THE FACT THAT THE
PAIN WAS WAITING WHEN WE GOT
BACK, I WAS SO EMOTIONAL AND THE
FACT THAT CHRIS TUCKER TOOK TWO
HOURS AND TOOK PEOPLE AWAY FROM
THE -- HE DID A GREAT SERVICE
FOR PEOPLE AND HE DEDICATED HIS
SHOW --
>> WE AIRED OUR SPECIAL FOR THE
SANDY VICTIMS FRIDAY AND ON THE
OTHER SHOW AND WE WERE THINKING
SHOULD WE DO A COMEDY SPECIAL
TONIGHT BUT THEN, YOU KNOW, IT
WAS FOR ANOTHER TRAGEDY, A
HURRICANE.
>> IF YOU HAD --
>> I HAD THE INTERVIEW WITH THE
PRESIDENT THIS PAST FRIDAY KEPT
TALKING ABOUT IT HERE WHICH WAS
SUCH A CHARMING INTERVIEW WITH
THE PRESIDENT AND FIRST LADY AND
I'M SORRY PEOPLE DIDN'T SEE IT
BUT IT SIMPLY WASN'T
APPROPRIATE.
I THINK THAT HAPPENED WITH A
LOT --
>> COMEDY IS A LITTLE BIT
DIFFERENT.
YOU HAVE THIS GIFT TO BE ABLE TO
TAKE PEOPLE AWAY FROM A LITTLE
BIT OF THE PAIN THEY'RE GOING
THROUGH AND I THINK IT WAS A
GREAT SERVICE OF YOUR SPECIAL OF
DOING COMEDY, BECAUSE LIKE I
SAID, WHEN YOU GET BACK IT'S ALL
WAITING RIGHT THERE.
>> THE CHURCH IS IN THE
NEIGHBORHOOD TO STAY ALL AROUND
DID A REMARKABLE JOB OF COMING
TOGETHER.
I THINK THE SENSE OF COMMUNITY
AND BEING ABLE TO, YOU KNOW,
RESTING GOD AND PROMISE AND I
THINK IS REALLY THE SOURCE OF
COMFORT FOR SO MANY RIGHT NOW
AND I THINK THEY ALL DID A
REMARKABLE JOB.
>> WELL, IT IS -- THE WORLD, THE
WORLD IS WATCHING.
THE WORLD IS GRIEVING WITH US
AND, YOU KNOW --
>> DIDN'T YOU HAVE KIDS OVER AT
YOUR HOUSE.
>> I HAD A LOT OF KIDS AT MY
HOUSE YESTERDAY BECAUSE I -- I
FEEL LIKE -- KIDS SHOULD HAVE
ONE DAY THAT'S MAGIC WHERE THEY
CAN COME AND NO MATTER WHAT ELSE
HAPPENS, THEY CAN BELIEVE IN
SOMETHING LIKE SANTA CLAUS OR  N
ORRINDEER COMING AND SO --
>> COME TO YOUR --
>> YES.
>> OTHER HOUSES -- WHEN JEFFREY
GOT ON HIS LAP HE LOOKED LIKE HE
WANTED TO CRY WHEN SANTA CLAUS
HUGGED HIM.
I THANK YOU BECAUSE YOU MADE
THAT A MAGICAL DAY FOR THOSE
CHILDREN THAT WERE THERE.
>> THIS TIME HE DID NOT COME
DOWN THE CHIMNEY BECAUSE THERE
WAS A FIRE IN THE CHIMNEY.
AND I DIDN'T WANT TO BE
RESPONSIBLE -- BUT HE SHOWED UP
IN A HORSE AND CARRIAGE
>> THAT'S OKAY.
>> AND LOTS OF LITTLE KIDS WERE
VERY HAPPY AND SOME OF OUR
FRIENDS WERE THE AREA THAT THIS
HORROR HAPPENED IN, AND SO IT
GAVE THEM A LITTLE BIT OF -- IT
WAS A GOOD DAY AND THERE WILL BE
OTHER GOOD DAYS.
WE'LL MAKE IT THROUGH THIS.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
>> Announcer: STILL AHEAD, ABC
NEWS CHIEF LOCAL CORRESPONDENT
CHRIS CUOMO IS BACK FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WITH THE
LATEST ON THE SHOCKING MASSACRE.
AND A FORENSIC PSYCHIATRIST IS
TAKING YOU INSIDE THE MIND OF
THE SHOOTER RESPONSIBLE FOR
THIS MASSACRE AND WHAT'S BEHIND
THIS TERRIFYING TREND OF GUNMEN
ON A RAMPAGE?
♪
SWEETIE,
WHY ARE YOU UP?
YOU'RE NOT FEELING WELL?
[ coughing ]
LET'S GO GET
SOME TRIAMINIC.
♪
[ Female Announcer ] OTHER COLD
AND COUGH MEDICINES CAN SETTLE.
TRIAMINIC
NIGHT TIME COLD & COUGH
HAS PERFECT MIX™ TECHNOLOGY...
SO THE MEDICINE IS ALWAYS
EVENLY DISTRIBUTED
TO HELP YOUR CHILD GET
THE RIGHT AMOUNT OF MEDICINE
EVERY TIME.
TO HELP THEM FEEL BETTER FAST,
TRUST IN TRIAMINIC.
[ Male Announcer ]
JILL AND HER MOUTH HAVE LIVED
A GREAT LIFE.
BUT SHE HAS SOME DENTAL ISSUES
SHE'S NOT HAPPY ABOUT.
SO JILL'S DENTIST
INTRODUCED HER
TO CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SELECTED FOR PEOPLE OVER 50.
PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE IS A
TOOTHPASTE THAT DEFENDS AGAINST
TENDER, INFLAMED GUMS,
SENSITIVITY AND WEAK ENAMEL.
CONDITIONS PEOPLE OVER 50
EXPERIENCE.
CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SO JILL CAN KEEP LIVING
THE GOOD LIFE.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
[ Female Announcer ]
CHARMIN ULTRA SOFT IS SO SOFT
YOU'LL HAVE TO REMIND
YOUR FAMILY THEY CAN USE LESS.
IT'S MADE WITH EXTRA CUSHIONS
THAT ARE SOFT
AND MORE ABSORBENT.
PLUS YOU CAN USE
FOUR TIMES LESS.
CHARMIN ULTRA SOFT.
I WAS TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
HOW I COULD GET RID OF
99% OF THE LEAD I CAN PICK UP,
AND THEN...
[ click ]
IT JUST CLICKED.
GET IT?
IT CLICKED...LIKE THE THING...
YOUR WATER SHOULD BE PUR.
[ Female Announcer ]
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA BARS,
RICH DARK CHOCOLATE,
TOASTED OATS.
PERFECT COMBINATIONS OF
NATURE'S DELICIOUS INGREDIENTS,
FROM NATURE VALLEY.
♪
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA BARS,
NATURE AT ITS MOST DELICIOUS.
♪
Almay Primer
The first step to a beautiful
look
A swirl of green correcting
your color
A twirl of lavender
"...brightening your glow"
Together, these two colors
create the perfect canvas
[ Woman #2 ]
IT'S THE REAL DEAL!
[ Man #1 ]
TURN IT AROUND! TURN IT AROUND!
[ Woman #1 ]
OVER HERE! OVER HERE!
[ Woman #2 ]
TURN AROUND! TURN AROUND!
[ Woman #1 ]
I LOVE YOU!
I CAN'T BELIEVE
IT'S NOT BUTTER!
NEITHER CAN I.
TURN THE TUB AROUND!
SHOW US THE BACK!
[ Man #1 ]
TURN THE TUB AROUND!
[ Female Announcer ]
WITH ZERO GRAMS
OF TRANS FAT PER SERVING,
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT'S NOT BUTTER
IS A SUPERSTAR!
♪
TURN THE TUB AROUND,
AND BECOME A BELIEVER.
[ Female Announcer ]
FOR EVERYTHING YOUR FACE
HAS TO FACE.
FACE IT
WITH PUFFS ULTRA SOFT & STRONG.
PUFFS HAS SOFT,
AIR-FLUFFED PILLOWS
FOR 40% MORE CUSHIONY
THICKNESS.
FACE EVERY DAY
WITH PUFFS SOFTNESS.
I'M HOME!
[ baby crying ]
EVERYTHING'S FINE.
[ Male Announcer ]
OF ALL THE THINGS THAT HAPPEN
ON YOUR WOODEN SURFACES,
DISINFECTING
HAS TO BE ONE OF THEM.
CLOROX DISINFECTING WIPES.
GENTLE ON WOOD.
HARD ON GERMS.
BECAUSE FOUR OUT OF FIVE DOGS
OVER THE AGE OF THREE
DEVELOP GUM DISEASE,
AND TARTAR BUILDUP
IS A CONTRIBUTING FACTOR.
[ Dog ] OR NEW DENTASTIX FRESH.
CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO FIGHT TARTAR
>> WHEN WE COME BACK, ABC NEWS
AND NOW WITH ADDED INGREDIEN
CHIEF LEGAL CORRESPONDENT CHRIS
>>> AMERICA AS WE'VE BEEN SAYING
IS STILL IN SHOCK FROM FRIDAY'S
TRAJ THAT LEFT 20 CHILDREN DEAD,
7 ADULTS.
AND CHRIS CUOMO IS HERE WHO JUST
RETURNED FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AND SADLY HAS
COVERED THESE KIND OF EVENTS
BEFORE.
SO WE GRIEVE AND THEN NOTHING
CHANGES.
>> NOTHING CHANGES.
AND WE FEEL POWERLESS AND I
DON'T BELIEVE THAT'S TRUE.
IN EVERY ONE OF THESE SINCE
COLUMBINE WE SEE A FORMULA.
THERE'S SOMEONE WHO IS DERANGED,
WHO HAS BECOME ISOLATED.
THEY FIND THE TOOLS THEY NEED,
OFTEN ASSAULT RIFLES AND THEN
THEY GO OUT AND SIN WHAT THEY SE
AS GLORY.
THE REASON IT'S RESONATING IS
NOT JUST BECAUSE SOME OF US HAVE
KIDS THAT AGE, IT WAS WHAT WAS
ATTACKED IS WHAT WE WANT TO
PROTECT THE MOST AND DONE IN A
WAY THAT WE BELIEVE COULD HAVE
BEEN PREVENTED.
THAT'S A TOUGH COMBINATION.
>> WHAT DO WE KNOW NOW ABOUT
THIS?
>> HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW.
WE WANT THIS NOT TO HAPPEN
AGAIN.
WE'RE ACHING FOR THAT.
IT'S LITERALLY HEART RENDING.
WE CAN DO THAT.
>> HOW?
>> YOU SHOULD HAVE ARMED
SECURITY IN SCHOOLS.
I DON'T LIKE THE IDEA.
I DON'T WANT MY KIDS TO BE
AFRAID WHEN THEY GO TO SCHOOL
BUT IN A PLACE LIKE THAT IT
DOESN'T HAPPEN.
>> YOU MEAN HAVE A POLICE --
>> BECAUSE WHAT DID WE HAVE
HERE?
THE SCHOOL WAS LOCKED, BARBARA.
THIS MAN --
>> HE BROKE IN.
>> HE BLEW OUT THE PLATE GLASS
WINDOW.
>> EVERY SCHOOL SHOULD HAVE
SECURITY GUARD WITH GUNS?
>> WHO CARES WHAT I SAY?
I'M TELLING YOU THIS, IN EVERY
ONE OF THE SITUATION THE ONLY
TIME IT IS STOPPED IS IF THERE
IS SOMEONE IN PLACE TO STOP IT
BEFORE.
WE KNOW THAT.
LOOK, WE DON'T LIKE THE
INSTRUCTIONS AND BRUTALITY.
WE WANT TO BE BETTER BUT IF YOU
WANT TO PROTECT THESE FROM
HAPPENING THAT'S HOW YOU DO IT.
LOOK AT 9/11, THE LESSON WE HAVE
TO DO BETTER AT OUR AIRPORTS.
WE CHANGED THE PROTOCOLS.
MANY FIND IT INCONVENIENT BUT WE
HAVEN'T HAD ANOTHER ATTACK LIKE
THAT AND WE HAVE TO THINK ABOUT
IT.
>> YOU CAN'T HAVE ARMED SECURITY
GUARDS AT MALLS AND THEATERS.
>> WHY?
>> EVERYWHERE.
>> YOU DON'T WANT TO BE PARANOID
BUT HAVE THE CONVERSATION.
YOU'RE NOT POWERLESS ABOUT THIS.
IF YOU WANT TO KNOW WHY IT
HAPPENS IT'S NOT JUST BECAUSE OF
THE GUN, OKAY.
IT WOULD BE NICE IF THERE WERE
NO GUNS.
IF THERE WERE NICE IF THERE WERE
NOT A LOT OF THINGS BUT IT'S NOT
GOING TO HAPPEN IN AMERICA.
>> SEEMS AS IF THESE PERPSS KILL
THEMSELVES AS SOON AS THE FIRST
RESPONDERS ARRIVE.
MAYBE THEY SHOULD HAVE A WAY TO
PICK UP A HOT LINE AND COME
IMMEDIATELY THEN THEY'LL SHOOT
THEMSELVES BEFORE THEY GET A
CHANCE TO SHOOT EVERYBODY ELSE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK OF THAT?
>> I THINK THAT I KIND OF HALF
UNDERSTAND WHAT YOU'RE SAYING --
>> WHICH PART DON'T YOU
UNDERSTAND?
>> I THINK THE INSTRUCTION IS
THIS, WHY DOES -- WHY DO THEY
KILL THEMSELVES?
THEY'RE SICK.
I DON'T WANT TO --
>> THEY KILL THEMSELVES BECAUSE
THEY DON'T WANT TO FACE PEOPLE
LIKE US.
>> JOY, THEY ARE SICK.
A HEALTHY-MINDED PERSON DOESN'T
DO SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
START THERE.
I DON'T ENGAGE IN THE DETAILS
WHY THIS GUY DID WHAT HE DID
BECAUSE IT'S NOT INSTRUCTIVE OF
ANYTHING.
THIS IS MADNESS.
YOU'RE DEALING WITH MADNESS.
THEY KILL THEMSELVES BECAUSE
THEY'RE DERANGED.
HE HAD ON A VEST EVEN THOUGH
HE'S GOING IN A KIDS' SCHOOL
BECAUSE HE THINKS HE'S GETTING
READY FOR BATTLE.
DR. MICHAEL WELNER IS HERE.
HE'LL EXPLAIN ALL THAT GOES INTO
THE PSYCHOSIS.
STOP THESE THINGS GOING FORWARD.
>> A LOT OF ELEMENTS GOING
FORWARD.
>> SPECIFICALLY ABOUT ADAM
LANZA'S CASE MAKES YOU OR SHOULD
MAKE US MORE AWARE ABOUT THESE
SITUATIONS.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW ABOUT HIM THAT
WE CAN USE AND EXTRACT TO SAY
THIS, THIS AND THIS NEEDS TO
HAPPEN.
>> WHAT BOTHERS ME MOST, HE'S
JUST LIKE THE OTHERS.
HE WAS KNOWN TO BE TROUBLED.
THEY COULDN'T GET THE RIGHT
TREATMENT.
HE ISOLATED HIMSELF.
THEY COULDN'T FIND ANYTHING TO
DO FOR HIM IN THE FAMILY.
>> WITH GUNS --
>> HE HAD A MOTHER WHO WAS A GUN
ENTHUSIAST.
SHE'S NOT UNLIKE MILLIONS OF
OTHER PEOPLE.
>> SHE'S GOT A KID WHO IS NUTS
AND SHE HAS ALL THESE GUNS IN
THE HOUSE.
>> WELL, FIRST OF ALL, JUST
BECAUSE YOU HAVE --
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> RIGHT, RIGHT, JUST BECAUSE --
LOOK, I DON'T LIKE CONDEMNING
SOMEBODY WHO ISN'T HERE ANYMORE
TO DEFEND THEMSELVES.
I DON'T KNOW HOW HE GOT THE
WEAPONS.
MAYBE YOU DO BUT I DO KNOW THIS
WE CANNOT ASSUME WHAT THIS WOMAN
KNEW ABOUT HER KID.
IT'S EASY FOR PEOPLE TO SAY, I
SAW IT COMING.
HE WAS ODD.
WELL, BUT YOU DIDN'T SAY
ANYTHING DID.
NOTHING ROOST LITTLE I DONE SO
LET'S NOT WHAT WAS PRESUMED TO
BE KNOWN NOW.
SHE IS GONE.
IT'S TERRIBLE.
SHE HAD WEAPONS.
DOESN'T MAKE HER A BAD PERSON.
HE GOT HIS HANDS ON THEM.
MAKES HIM DANGEROUS BECAUSE HE
IS MAD, INSANE.
>> CHRIS, I KNOW YOU'RE SAYING
HE IS DERANGED.
WHAT OTHER MOTIVE DO YOU THINK
HE HAD TO GO IN AND SLAUGHTER
THESE ADULTS AND CHILDREN?
>> IT'S A PRESSING QUESTION.
WE HAVE TO KNOW BECAUSE WE HAVE
TO MAKE SENSE BECAUSE OTHERWISE
IT HURTS TOO MUCH.
I GET IT.
I'M OF A LITTLE DIFFERENT MIND
BECAUSE I'VE BEEN IN SO MANY
DIFFERENT SITUATIONS.
WHAT THIS HAPPENED, I SAID WE'LL
FIND OUT HE'S MENTALLY ILL, HE
HAD ACCESS TO THESE WEAPONS AND
HE HAD A BEEF AND HE SAW THIS --
NOW, THIS IS THE BIGGEST REASON
I CAME ON THE SHOW TODAYERS
OTHERWISE, SEEING YOU WEIR IS
ALWAYS A PLEASURE.
THERE'S AN ELEPHANT IN THE ROOM,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
WE HAVE A CULTURE OF VIOLENCE.
THIS DOESN'T HAPPEN IN OTHER
COUNTRIES AND IT'S NOT BECAUSE
OF THE WEAPONS.
PEOPLE IN THIS CULTURE
BELIEVE -- ALBEIT CRAZY PEOPLE,
BELIEVE THE WAY TO GO OUT WITH
GLORY IS TO KILL BECAUSE I WILL
BE RESPECTED.
I WILL BE THE MAN LIKE CHO SAID
AT VIRGINIA TECH AND THEY'RE
WRONG BUT THEY'RE WRONG AND WHAT
DO WE DO ABOUT IT?
IT'S IN OUR CULTURE.
IT BENEFITS LIKE PEOPLE LIKE ME.
I GOT INTO SCHOOL BECAUSE I
COULD RUN FAST AND KNOCK PEOPLE
DONE.
THE CULTURE IS ALL AROUND US.
YOU'RE IN THIS CONSTANT.
THE KID WANTS IT, SHOULD HE REEL
BE BE WITH A WEAPON KILLING AS
MANY PEOPLE AS POSSIBLE?
IS THAT WHAT HE SHOULD BE?
>> YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT GUN,
MEDIA, VIDEO --
>> I THINK IT'S THIS.
HERE'S WHY I THINK IT, OKAY.
MY OPINIONS ARE MEANINGLESS.
EVERYTHING I SAY IS BECAUSE WHAT
I HAVE OBSERVED.
IF YOU LOOK AT OTHER COUNTRIES
THEY HAVE LOTS OF MENTALLY ILL
PEOPLE.
THEY HAVE WEAPONS.
YOU KNOW, WE'RE NOT CAVEMEN IN
AMERICA.
>> WHAT YOU MEAN, SHERRI SAID
VIDEO GAMES, MOVIES.
>> I THINK THERE'S SOMETHING
ABOUT OUR CULTURE THAT BREEDS A
TENDENCY TO BELIEVE THAT
VIOLENCE IS GLORIFYING.
AND WE SEE IT --
>> THE TELEVISION COVERAGE THAT
WE GIVE EVERYTHING.
>> IT COULD BE.
IT COULD BE.
IT IS A LOT OF THINGS.
BUT, LOOK, THIS IS THE HOPE.
THE HOPE IS THIS, THINGS DO NOT
HAVE TO STAY THE WAY THEY ARE.
HOPEFULLY GOD FORBID WE WILL
NEVER SEE SOMETHING LIKE THIS
AGAIN BUT WE ARE NOT POWERLESS.
WHO GETS WEAPONS AND HOW IS A
LEGITIMATE CONVERSATION.
THERE IS NO REAL PROOF THAT GUN
LAWS CHANGE GUN CRIME BUT IT'S A
GOOD CONVERSATION.
A CONVERSATION ABOUT WHO THEY
ARE AND WHAT WE ENFORCE AND THE
VALUES OF THE PEOPLE AROUND US.
>> WHO WE VOTE FOR.
>> IT BECOMES PART OF IT.
YOU PICK THE PEOPLE WOULD
REFLECT YOUR VALUES BUT HOW WE
TREAT THE MENTALLY ILL, IT USED
TO BE -- IN 1970, 1 IN EVERY 100
PEOPLE IN THE UNITED STATES WAS
IN AN ASYLUM.
NOW WITHIN 72 HOURS OF PUTTING
SOMEBODY INTO INCARCERATION YOU
HAVE TO PROVE THEY'RE A DANGER
TO THEMSELVES OR SOMEBODY ELSE.
HIGH STANDARD.
NINE OUT OF TEN TIMES THEY'RE
RELEASED AND YOU HAVE SOMEONE  N
UNMONITORED.
>> ACCESS TO AN AUTOMATIC RIFLE.
THAT'S THE SICK PART.
>> WHO MAY OR MAY NOT.
>> NOT ONLY THAT THEY'RE CRAZY
BUT CAN GET THIS GUN, THAT
DRIVES ME NUTS.
>> WHAT WE'RE SAYING IT'S NOT
JUST ONE THING.
IF IT IS A CULTURE OF VIOLENCE I
DON'T KNOW HOW YOU CHANGE AN
ENTIRE CULTURE.
BUT THE PRESIDENT SAID TOO
SOMETHING HAS TO BE DONE.
>> WE CAN DO BETTER.
>> NOW WE HAVE TO -- WHETHER
IT'S GUNS, WHETHER IT'S MORE
ATTENTION TO THOSE WHO HAVE
MENTAL PROBLEMS, WHETHER IT'S A
DIFFERENT THING IN THE WAY YOU
BRING UP -- WHATEVER IT IS, IT
IS A LARGER SUBJECT AND WE
HOPE --
>> WE CAN DO BETTER, BARBARA,
AND THE WAY TO DO THAT DO IT
EVERY WAY YOU POSSIBLY CAN.
WE WANT TO THOSE WHO ARE GONE.
WE WANT TO HONOR THE FAMILIES.
>> WE'LL DISCUSS MORE ABOUT WHAT
POSSIBLY THE MOTIVE COULD BE AND
HOW COULD YOU RECOGNIZE
SOMETHING WITHIN YOUR OWN
NEIGHBORHOOD OR YOUR OWN FAMILY.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
>> Announcer: UP NEXT, A
FORENSIC PSYCHIATRIST IS TAKING
YOU INSIDE THE TWISTED MINDS
RESPONSIBLE TORE THIS RAMPAGE
AND TELLING YOU WHY THESE
SHOOTING RAMPAGES HAVE BECOME A
DISTURBING TREND IN HEADLINES
AROUND THE WORLD.
[ Male Announcer ]
NO MATTER WHAT CITY
YOU'RE PLAYING TOMORROW.
[ coughs ]
♪
YOU CAN'T LET A COLD
KEEP YOU UP TONIGHT.
[ snores ]
VICKS NYQUIL.
POWERFUL NIGHTTIME 6-SYMPTOM
COLD & FLU RELIEF.
♪
[ sniffles, coughs ]
EXCUSE ME.
I NEED SOMETHING FOR
MY COLD SYMPTOMS. [ sniffles ]
WE'VE GOT DAYQUIL FOR DAY
AND NYQUIL FOR NIGHT.
[ thuds ]
YOU DIDN'T SEE THAT.
[ Male Announcer ]
RIGHT NOW AT WALGREENS
DAYQUIL AND NYQUIL
ARE JUST $10.99 WITH CARD.
[ Male Announcer ]
RIGHT NOW AT WALGREENS
GO DELICIOUS!
EXPERIENCE
OLIVE GARDEN'S
NEW PARMESAN CRUSTED
STUFFED CHICKEN
WITH SUNDRIED TOMATOES,
CREAMY ALFREDO,
AND OUR SIGNATURE
BLEND OF CHEESES.
OR DIG INTO OUR NEW STUFFED
CHICKEN WITH SAUTEED SHRIMP.
GO OLIVE GARDEN!
♪
[Spider-Man]
WE GOT THIS.
♪
[Mom]
THIS HERO STUFF IS EASY!
YOU'RE ONLY GOOD AT ONE THING.
WELL, THERE'S MORE TO ME
THAN THAT.
I CAN HANDLE SPLATTERS
AND SPILLS.
I EVEN KILL BACTERIA.
SMUDGY RESIDUE -- NOT ME.
I GIVE YOU MORE WAYS TO SHINE.
Windex.
Challenge that with new Olay
Facial Hair Removal Duo.
A two-step process that removes
even coarse, stubborn
facial hair gently.
Plenty of gain,
without all that pain...
With Olay.
[ Female Announcer ]
HOLIDAY COOKIES ARE A BIG JOB.
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE
JUST RIGHT.
PERFECTION IS IN THE DETAILS.
♪
GET TO HOLIDAY FUN FASTER
WITH PILLSBURY COOKIE DOUGH.
YOUR MOUTH HAS BEEN
SNACKING, GIFT STACKING,
NUTCRACKING AND YELLOWING.
BECAUSE IF YOU'RE NOT
WHITENING, YOU'RE YELLOWING.
CREST WHITESTRIPS
REMOVE OVER 10 YEARS OF STAINS,
JUST IN TIME
FOR A WHITE HOLIDAY.
CREST 3D WHITE WHITESTRIPS.
JUST IN TIME
FOR A WHITE HOLIDAY.
OH, IT'S GREAT!
NOW I CAN BREW MY COFFEE
JUST THE WAY I LOVE IT.
HOW DO YOU DO THAT?
WELL, INSIDE THE BREWER,
THERE'S THIS TRAIN
THAT'S POWERFUL ENOUGH
TO CARRY MORE COFFEE
AND FRESH WATER TO MAKE COFFEE
THAT'S STRONGER
AND BIGGER...
AND EVEN HOTTER!
ACTUALLY, I JUST PRESS
THIS BUTTON.
BREW THE COFFEE YOU LOVE --
STRONGER, BIGGER, OR HOTTER --
WITH THE KEURIG VUE.
♪
>>> EVERYONE IS, OF COURSE,
ASKING THEMSELVES WHAT KIND OF
PERSON COULD DO THIS AND HOW
DOES A PARENT EVEN BEGIN TO
EXPLAIN IT TO THEIR KIDS SO
RIGHT NOW WE ARE GETTING INSIGHT
FROM THE CHAIRMAN OF THE
FORENSIC PAM WHO EXAMINES SOME
OF THE MOST COMPLEX HOMICIDES IN
AMERICA.
FORENSIC PSYCHIATRIST DR.
MICHAEL WELNER.
WE'LL GET RIGHT TO IT.
DROVE FIVE MILES TO THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL TO
SLAUGHTER 20 FIRST GRADERS.
AND 6 ADULTS AND I THINK
EVERYONE IS JUST ASKING, PARENT
OR NOT, LIKE HOW DOES SOMETHING
LIKE THIS HAPPEN?
>> WELL --
>> WHAT'S THE MIND-SET.
>> I WANT TO PERHAPS PUT
EVERYBODY AT EASE BY SAYING THIS
IS THE END POINT OF A PATHWAY,
BUT LET'S RECOGNIZE THAT IT'S
PATHWAY AND THERE ARE PLACES
WHERE WE COULD INTERSECT AND
INTERVENE TO MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
IT STARTS WITH SOMEONE WHO IS
FUNDAMENTALLY RESENTFUL AND
ALIENATED AND BLAMES OTHERS, ALL
RIGHT.
AND THEN IT PROGRESSES FROM
THERE TO SOMEONE WHO IDENTIFIES
WITH THE IDEA OF DESTRUCTION AS
A MATTER OF STATURE AND THEN THE
PERSON BECOMES INCREASINGLY
WITHDRAWN AS THEY GET A LITTLE
OLDER AND THEY HAVE SOCIAL OR
SEXUAL FRUSTRATION AND
INCOMPETENCE AND THEN FROM THERE
THEY BECOME AND THIS IS A KEY
STEP, THEY BECOME INVESTED IN
THE IDEA OF BLAMING EVERYBODY
AROUND THEM.
ALONG THE WAY, THE 24-HOUR NEWS
CYCLE IS TAKING THESE PEOPLE WHO
ARE ANGRY AT THE WORLD ANDBURG
THEM UP AS LARGER THAN LIFE AS
WE SAW THE PICTURE BEHIND HIM
AND OTHERWISE WOULD BE A TOTALLY
UNREMARKABLE PERSON AND IDENTIFY
WITH THE MASS KILLER AND THEN
AND I WANT TO COMPLIMENT THE
CONNECTICUT POLICE FOR DOING
THIS, THEY KNOW WHAT HE SAYS HIS
MOTIVE IS.
THEY'RE NOT TELLING US AND
THAT'S CORRECT.
BECAUSE WHAT --
>> WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
IN THEY'VE BEEN ON HIS COMPUTER.
THEY KNOW WHAT HE WROTE.
THIS IS INDEFENSIBLE.
THERE IS NO GRIEVANCE.
JUST LET ME MAKE THIS POINT.
HE SEES AND THAT COULD BE A
PERSON WATCHING THIS PROGRAM
WHICH IS CHILLING, COULD BE A
CHILD OF ANYBODY IN THIS ROOM
WHO SAYS, YOU KNOW WHAT, HE SEES
US SAYING WE FAILED.
WE FAILED AND HE TAPS INTO THE
IDEA THAT PEOPLE DESERVE THIS
AND THERE ARE A FEW INDIVIDUALS
OUT THERE AND THIS IS
IRRESPECTIVE OF MENTALLY
ILLNESS.
SOME OF THEM ARE ILL.
SOME OF THEM ARE NOT.
THEY ADOPT IT AS AN AMBITION.
THIS IS NOT ABOUT A MENTALLY
ILLNESS OF THIS IS ABOUT A LIFE
CHOICE.
A PERSON MAKES A LIFE CHOICE
THAT AT SOME POINT HE IS GOING
TO BE A MASS KILLER AND WHEN
THAT HAPPENS, IT'S A QUESTION OF
DETERMINATION OF WHEN IS THAT
GOING TO HAPPEN?
AND HE BEGINS TO PLAN, NONE OF
IT IT SPONTANEOUS.
>> HE'S NOT MENTALLY ILL.
>> SOME OF THEM AREN'T AND SOME
OF THEM ARE.
MY POINT IS IT'S A LIFE CHOICE
THAT A PERSON WITH AN ILLNESS
MAKE.
HUNTERS BREIVIK MADE A LIFE
CHOICE AND PLANNED EXTENSIVELY
AND WHEN HE DECIDED MY LIFE IS A
FAILURE --
>> WELL, THAT INDIVIDUAL --
>> THIS IS A PATHWAY.
>> BUT I HAVE TWO QUESTIONS.
NUMBER ONE IS WHY DO THEY TARGET
CHILDREN?
AND, NUMBER TWO, IF YOU SEE
SOMETHING LIKE THIS IN YOUR
FAMILY AND PEOPLE HAVE BEEN
TALKING ABOUT IT NOW, WHAT DO
YOU DO?
SOME OF THE MOTHERS HAVE SAID WE
SEE THIS, WE KNOW THIS BUT WE
DON'T GET ANY HELP AND YOU CAN'T
ARREST THIS PERSON.
WHAT DO YOU DO?
>> WELL, I WANT TO ADDRESS TWO
POINTS.
FIRST OF ALL, THE MAJOR MYTH OF
THIS THAT WE'RE ALL MAKING A
MISTAKE ABOUT IS TO FOCUS ON
GUNS AND MENTAL HEALTH AT THE
BOTTOM OF THIS.
GUNS MAY MAKE THINGS WORSE, GUNS
MAY BE A CONTRIBUTOR.
SOME PEOPLE ARE MENTALLY ILL AND
DESERVE HELP AND AREN'T GETTING
IT, I GET IT BUT THAT'S NOT WHY
THIS IS HAPPENING.
GUNS HAVE BEEN AROUND FOR A LONG
TIME.
JUST A MINUTE.
LET ME EXPLAIN.
THIS IS A KEY POINT.
WE'RE SEEING A PROLIFERATION.
IT'S GOING TO HAPPEN AGAIN.
IT'S GOING TO GET WORSE AND IT'S
GOING TO TARGET CHILDREN.
WHY?
>> WHY?
>> BECAUSE YOU'RE SHOCKED AND
YOU'LL TALK ABOUT IT.
WHEN SOMEBODY DOES A SHOOTING AT
THE WORKPLACE, THE NEWS MEDIA
DOESN'T TALK ABOUT IT ANYMORE.
BUT IF WE'RE SHOCKED ENOUGH
EVERYBODY IS GOING TO ASK, WHO
IS THIS CLOWN?
WHO IS THIS PERVERT?
>> HE'S DEAD.
>> BUT THAT'S NOT THE POINT.
THE POINT IS THAT HE HAS DECIDED
THAT HE WANTS TO HAVE A LEGACY
WHICH IS GIVEN TO HIM BY
TREMENDOUS INTEREST IN HIM AND
WHAT HE IS ABOUT SO SHOCK IS THE
REASON AND ALSO THESE
INDIVIDUALS KNOW THE BIGGER THE
BODY COUNT, THE MORE LIKELY
THERE'S NEWS MEDIA COVERAGE.
WHAT IS IT ABOUT SMALL CHILDREN?
THEY'RE DEFENSELESS.
THEY'RE DEFENSELESS AND THAT'S
WHY A PERSON TAKES A
HIGH-CALIBER AUTOMATIC WEAPON
BECAUSE YOU CAN KILL MORE AND
BECAUSE THE CHILDREN ARE
DEFENSELESS AND SO WE WILL GIVE
THEM RELEVANCE.
>> DOCTOR, WE WANT YOU TO STICK
WITH US IF YOU CAN.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH MORE ON
THIS.
THANK YOU.
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
DISCOVER THE TEMPTING LAYERS
OF FERRERO ROCHER.
A WHOLE HAZELNUT,
SMOOTH CHOCOLATY CREAM
INSIDE A WAFER SHELL,
COVERED IN MILK CHOCOLATE
AND HAZELNUT PIECES.
♪
FERRERO ROCHER.
MAKE YOUR MOMENTS GOLDEN.
OOH-HOO, I CAN'T WAIT TO CLEAN
SOMETHING BESIDES THE SHOWER.
[ Male Announcer ]
Scrubbing Bubbles' FOAM
PENETRATES TOUGH GRIME
AND KILLS 99.9% OF BACTERIA,
SO CLEANING THE WHOLE BATHROOM
IS EASIER.
Scrubbing Bubbles.
[ Female Announcer ]
SC Johnson.
Oh, did you want it?
Yea
We'll split it.
[ Female Announcer ]
Made fresh, so light,
buttery and flakey.
That's half
That's not half!
Guys, I have more!
Thanks Mom
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Crescents.
Let the Making Begin
♪
[ Male Announcer ] CAMPBELL'S
GREEN BEAN CASSEROLE.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO
YOUR MOUTH HAS BEEN
SNACKING, GIFT STACKING,
NUTCRACKING AND YELLOWING.
BECAUSE IF YOU'RE NOT
WHITENING, YOU'RE YELLOWING.
CREST WHITESTRIPS
REMOVE OVER 10 YEARS OF STAINS,
JUST IN TIME
FOR A WHITE HOLIDAY.
CREST 3D WHITE WHITESTRIPS.
CHECK THIS OUT.
BOO-YAH!
H2...O!
MAGIC BANANAS!
IT'S OUR FIRST
ONE CLICK FAUCET FILTER
THAT REMOVES 99%
OF LEAD AND MICROBIAL CYSTS.
ADIOS CONTAMINOS!
YOUR WATER SHOULD BE PUR.
>>> THIS IS TAYLOR FROM GEORGIA.
>> "THE VIEW" WILL RETURN ON
ABC.
>>> WE ARE BACK WITH FORENSIC
PSYCHIATRIST DR. MICHAEL WELNER.
DR. WELNER, THEY SAY ADAM LANZA
MAY HAVE BEEN MENTALLY ILL.
HE MAY HAVE HAD A PERSONALITY
DISORDER.
THERE WERE REPORTS THAT HE WAS
AUTISTIC.
IN THIS WHOLE THING, WHERE DOES
MENTALLY ILLNESS HAVE A ROLE?
>> WELL, THIS IS BASED ON MY
EXPERIENCE IN WORKING IN CASES
WHERE PEOPLE EITHER KILLED
THEMSELVES OR HAVING HAD THE
OPPORTUNITY TO SIT AND NOT ONLY
STUDY CASES BUT TO INTERVIEW
PEOPLE WHO CARRIED OUT MASS
SHOOTINGS, THERE ARE THREE
SYMPTOMS THAT ARE THE MOST
IMPORTANT ISSUE TO CONCERN
ONESELF WITH.
ONE IS SUSPICION AND RESENT.
TWO, HOPELESSNESS AND THREE IS
IDENTIFICATION WITH DESTRUCTION.
JUST A FASCINATION WITH
DESTRUCTION.
NOW, NONE OF THAT IS PART OF
AUTISM.
>> NO.
>> SO YOU ASK THE QUESTION, WHAT
IS ONE THING -- WELL, HERE'S
WHAT MAY PROVE TO BE AN ISSUE.
THAT SOMEONE WHO IS DIAGNOSED
WITH A DEVELOPMENTAL DISABILITY
MAY HAVE GREAT DIFFICULTY
COMMUNICATES SO IF HE WAS AT A
PLACE WHERE HE WAS BECOMING ILL
AND HAD SOMETHING IN WHICH THESE
SYMPTOMS WERE PART OF HIS
ILLNESS IT MIGHT HAVE BEEN
HARDER TO DETECT BECAUSE HE WAS
PECULIAR OR HE RELATED
DIFFERENTLY AND IT WOULD NOT
HAVE BEEN EASY TO WITNESS A
CHANGE.
NOW, AGAIN, WE KNOW VERY LITTLE
BUT THIS IS -- AUTISM IS NOT THE
ISSUE BUT AUTISM MAY HAVE BEEN
THE CLOAK THAT MAY HAVE MADE IT
DIFFICULT FOR EVEN SOMEONE WHO
CARED AND LOVED HIM SO MUCH TO
KEEP THIS FROM BEING DISCOVERED.
>> WHAT DO YOU THINK OF THE
MOTHER, THAT --
>> THIS IS A WOMAN WHO WAS SHOT
FIVE TIMES IN THE FACE.
I HAVE NOTHING TERRIBLE TO SAY
ABOUT HER.
WE MAY FIND SHE TRIED TO BE A
HERO TO STOP THIS AND BASICALLY
SHE WAS STANDING IN FRONT OF HIM
AND SAID YOU HAVE TO GO THROUGH
ME AND HE DID AND SO I THINK WE
NEED TO RESPECT THE DEAD.
THAT'S MY POSITION ON THAT.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> WE SPOKE ABOUT THIS EARLIER
TOO.
ULTIMATELY WHY DOES THIS
CONTINUE TO HAPPEN AND THEN HOW
DO WE PREVENT IT IT FROM
HAPPENING.
>> HERE'S A KEY THING TO LEARN,
AGAIN, THIS IS A PHENOMENON
THAT'S EXPLODED OVER THE PAST 20
YEARS OR SO, BECAUSE GUNS AND
MENTAL HEALTH HAVE BEEN AROUND
MUCH LONGER.
TWO KEY INGREDIENTS.
ONE IS A 24-HOUR COMPETITIVE
NEWS CYCLE THAT CAN TAKE PEOPLE
FROM BEING COMPLETELY ANONYMOUS
IN A CELEBRITY-DRIVEN CULTURE
WHICH DISTINGUISHES AMERICA AND
MAKE THEM LARGER THAN LIFE.
AND SO THAT'S ONE INGREDIENT.
THE OTHER IS WE HAVE BECOME
BETTER AT MAKING ESCAPISM
PERFECT AND SO NOW WE HAVE AN
INDUSTRY, VIDEOTAPE GAME
VIOLENCE THAT ESSENTIALLY FEEDS
ADDICTION IN A WAY THAT THE
TOBACCO COMPANIES BUILT A BETTER
NICOTINE AND A BETTER CIGARETTE
THAT IT BECOMES A DRUG SO FOR
SOMEONE ALREADY ISOLATED WHO IS
ALREADY DEVELOPMENTALLY DISABLED
WHO ALREADY HAS DIFFICULTY
CONNECTING, THE WORST THING YOU
CAN DO AND THIS IS SOME ADVICE
TO PARENTS WHICH WE'LL TOUCH ON
IN A MINUTE IS TO ALLOW THAT
ISOLATION TO BE PERPETUATED
ESPECIALLY IN A MEDIUM THAT
GIVES POINTS TO KILLING PEOPLE
THAT -- THINK ABOUT IT.
THIS WAS A CRIME THAT'S MORE
THAN A MASS SHOOTING, HE KILLED
THESE PEOPLE LIKE AN ARCADE
GAME.
WHO FILLS PEOPLE UP WITH 11
BULLETS AND 5 BULL FETES?
MEDICAL EXAMINERS, I WILL TELL
YOU AS A FWREN SICK SCIENTIST WE
DON'T SEE THAT.
THAT IS THE END POINT OF DEHUMAN
ASIAN.
IT'S JUST LIKE GUNS.
SOME PEOPLE CAN HANDLE IT.
SOME PEOPLE CAN'T.
YOUR CHILDREN DO NOT BENEFIT AT
ALL CONSTRUCTIVELY FROM VIDEO
GAME VIOLENCE.
STOP ALLOWING YOUR KIDS ACCESS
JUST AS YOU WOULDN'T GIVE THEM
ACCESS TO COCAINE.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> AND --
>> WHAT ABOUT TALKING --
>> WELL, I WANT TO END OR AT
LEAST MAKE AN OPTIMISTIC NOTE.
I CAN TELL YOU UNRESERVEDLY THIS
IS BASED ON EXPERIENCE I CAN'T
SAY THIS ABOUT ALL HOMICIDES.
MASS HOMICIDE IS A SOCIAL
PHENOMENON.
IT WILL GET WORSE AND IT COULD
BE TOTALLY ELIMINATED AND EACH
OF US CAN MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
>> HOW?
>> EXAMPLE, PARENTS, TEACH YOUR
CHILDREN AT THE BEGINNING TO
TAKE PERSONAL RESPONSIBILITY.
IF THEY DON'T START BLAMING
OTHERS THEY'LL NEVER GET THERE.
TEACH YOUR CHILDREN RESILIENCE,
WHEN THEY'RE HOPELESS, TEACH
THEM SOME PEOPLE GET UP.
TEACH THEM SOME PEOPLE WILL GO
FORWARD.
KEEP THEM AWAY FROM VIDEO GAME
VIOLENCE.
>> KEEP THEM OUT OF THE HOUSE.
PARENT WHO ARE PLAYING WITH
THEIR --
>> DON'T PAY FOR VIOLENCE.
WHY SHOULD YOU BE PAYING UPON
FOR YOUR CHILDREN TO SEE A
VIOLENT MOVIE.
IF YOU TAKE THE ECONOMY OUT OF
THE VIOLENCE INDUSTRY, YOU WILL
EXTINGUISH IT.
YOU WILL EXTINGUISH IT.
THEY'RE SEEING FEEDING THE
BEAST.
SECOND, WHAT CAN NEIGHBORS DO?
WHAT CAN NEIGHBORS DO?
GIVE AN EXAMPLE OF SUPPORTING
STRANGERS.
MODEL EMPATHY BECAUSE KIDS MAY
NOT GET IT IN THEIR OWN HOME.
IF YOU TEACH PEOPLE HOW TO HAVE
REGARD FOR SOMEONE WHO IS
STRUGGLING, AGAIN, KEEP IN MIND
THESE ARE INDIVIDUALS WHO ARE
CRAWLING INTO THE CRACKS.
NEXT WHAT CAN TEACHERS DO?
APART FROM TEACHING YOUR KIDS
RESILIENCE, TEACH THEM TO VALUE
CREATIVITY, TEACH THEM TO VALUE
VOLUNTEERISM AS HOW YOU GAIN
STRUCTURE BECAUSE IF PEOPLE ARE
CREATING AND THEY'RE VALUING
CREATIVITY THEY ARE NOT
DESTROYING.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> DR. WELNER, THANK YOU SO
MUCH.
WE WANT TO THANK DR. MICHAEL
WELNER AND CHRIS CUOMO.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH
"PRIVATE PRACTICE" STAR KADEE
STRICKLAND.
[ APPLAUSE ]
E COMES.
YOU WOULDN'T WANT YOUR
DOCTOR DOING YOUR JOB,
THE PITCH!
WHOA!
SO WHY ARE YOU DOING HIS?
ONLY YOUR DOCTOR CAN DETERMINE
IF YOUR PERSISTENT HEARTBURN
IS ACTUALLY SOMETHING
MORE SERIOUS
LIKE ACID REFLUX DISEASE.
OVER TIME, STOMACH
ACID CAN DAMAGE
THE LINING OF YOUR ESOPHAGUS.
FOR MANY, PRESCRIPTION NEXIUM
NOT ONLY PROVIDES
24-HOUR HEARTBURN RELIEF,
BUT CAN ALSO HELP HEAL
ACID-RELATED EROSIONS IN
THE LINING OF YOUR ESOPHAGUS.
THERE IS RISK OF BONE FRACTURE
AND LOW MAGNESIUM LEVELS.
SIDE EFFECTS MAY INCLUDE
HEADACHE, ABDOMINAL
PAIN AND DIARRHEA.
CALL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY IF
YOU HAVE PERSISTENT DIARRHEA.
OTHER SERIOUS STOMACH
CONDITIONS MAY EXIST.
DON'T TAKE NEXIUM IF
YOU TAKE CLOPIDOGREL.
LET YOUR DOCTOR DO HIS JOB.
AND YOU DO YOURS.
ASK IF NEXIUM IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
IF YOU CAN'T AFFORD
YOUR MEDICATION,
ASTRAZENECA MAY BE ABLE TO HELP.
[ ding! ]
LOSING YOUR CHEX MIX TOO EASILY?
TIME TO DEPLOY THE
BORING-POPCORN DECOY BUCKET.
THEN NO ONE WILL WANT TO STEAL
THE DELICIOUSNESS.
WITH A VARIETY OF TASTES
AND TEXTURES
ONLY CHEX MIX
IS A BAG OF INTERESTING.
WITH A VARIETY OF TASTES
AND TEXTURES
♪
Get her 1/3rd carat
diamond earrings
this week only just $29.99.
And save 75 to 80% on
all Fashion Diamonds.
At Kmart.
Whatever it takes, get to
Sears Last Minute Gift Sale.
Don't judge me!
Get 50% off sleepwear for
her, and more with pass.
Save up to 70% off
all diamonds,
and up to 30% off all Small
Kitchen Appliances.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
AHH, CLOUDY GLASSES.
YOU DIDN'T
HAVE TO COME OVER!
EASY.
HI. CASCADE KITCHEN COUNSELOR.
LOOK!
OVER TIME, CASCADE COMPLETE PACS
FIGHT FILM BUILDUP TWO TIMES
BETTER THAN FINISH QUANTUM
TO HELP LEAVE GLASSES SPARKLING.
CASCADE. THE CLEAR CHOICE.
DELICIOUS HERSHEY'S CHOCOLATEH,
WITH 30% LESS FAT?
HERSHEY'S SIMPLE
PLEASURES CHOCOLATE.
30% LESS FAT, 100% DELICIOUS.
I JUST WISH
I COULD KEEP IT THIS WAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
NOW YOU CAN.
WITH THE CREST PRO-HEALTH
CLINICAL LINE.
USED TOGETHER,
THEY HELP KEEP YOUR TEETH
97% AS CLEAN
AS A DENTAL CLEANING.
THE TOOTHPASTE
ACTUALLY REDUCES PLAQUE.
AND THE RINSE REACHES ALL AREAS
AND IS CLINICALLY PROVEN TO
HELP PREVENT PLAQUE REGROWTH.
CREST PRO-HEALTH CLINICAL LINE.
TOGETHER, THEY HELP KEEP
YOUR TEETH
97% AS CLEAN
AS A DENTAL CLEANING.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>>> THE ENTIRE COUNTRY IS SO
OVERWHELMED BY THE TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE HAPPY TO HAVE A GOOD
FRIEND HERE TO TAKE OUR MINDS
OFF OF THIS FOR AT LEAST A FEW
MINUTES.
PLEASE WELCOME BACK
OUR DEAREST FRIEND,
"PRIVATE PRACTICE" STAR KADEE
STRICKLAND.
[ APPLAUSE ]
HEY.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> KADEE, GIRL --
>> YOU LOOK LIKE A BULB ON A
TREE.
GOLD ON, SPARKLE?
>> THAT'S JUST WHAT WE NEED.
THAT GOOD OLD SOUTHERN SMILE AND
CHARM YOU HAVE.
WE JUST WANT TO WISH YOU FIRST
OFF A HAPPY BIRTHDAY, GIRL.
>> THANK YOU.
IT WAS FRIDAY.
>> IT WAS FRIDAY BUT WE HEARD
YOU POSTPONED IT BECAUSE YOU
WANTED TO WAIT TILL YOU GOT TO
NEW YORK.
>> I'M IN NEW YORK AND I HAVEN'T
BEEN HERE IN TEN YEARS.
I USED TO LIVE HERE BUT I
HAVEN'T BEEN HERE FOR THIS TIME
OF YEAR.
IT'S JUST MAGIC.
YOU DRIVE INTO THE CITY AND IT'S
JUST LIKE, AH.
YEAH.
>> BEAUTIFUL TO BE HERE.
>> YOU MAKE IT THAT MUCH
BRIGHTER TOO.
I KNOW -- SORRY, BARBARA.
>> THAT'S OKAY.
SO "PRIVATE PRACTICE" HAS BEEN
ON FOR SIX YEARS AND IT'S
ENDING.
>> IT'S ENDING.
>> SO HOW ARE YOU SMILING?
>> I KNOW.
I KNOW.
IT'S REMARKABLE.
I'VE BEEN A PART OF SOMETHING
THAT HAS BEEN ON THE AIR FOR SIX
SEASONS WHICH NEVER REALLY
HAPPENS ANYMORE AND DID 111
EPISODES AND TO HAVE BEEN A PART
OF A SHOW WITH THAT CAST AND
THAT -- SHONDA RHIMES --
>> SHE'LL WRITE SOMETHING ELSE
FOR YOU.
>> I'LL NEVER SAY NO TO THAT.
I CAN SAY WITH GREAT CLARITY.
TO BE ON A SHOW THAT TACKLES
ISSUES THAT ANYONE FROM AROUND
THE WORLD CAN TURN ON AND GO, I
KNOW WHAT IT'S LIKE TO HAVE
CANCER, I KNOW WHAT IT'S LIKE TO
HAVE BEEN SEXUALLY ASSAULTED.
I KNOW WHAT IT'S IKE TO ADOPT A
CHILD, TO HAVE FERTILITY ISSUES,
TO BE A PART OF THAT IS
REMARKABLE.
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHAT SIZE YOU
ARE, WHAT AGE YOU ARE, WHAT YOU
HAVE GOING ON IN YOUR LIFE
SHONDA PUTS IT ON THE SCREEN AND
FOR ME TO BE A PART OF THAT IS
THE THING I'M MOST PROUD OF.
>> YOUR MOM IS A NURSE.
>> SHE IS.
>> DID SHE WATCH THE SHOW?
WHAT DID SHE THINK ABOUT YOUR
DOCTORING SKILLS?
>> SHE'S VERY SUPPORTIVE OF ME,
THANK GOD.
WHAT'S NURSING SHE TAUGHT IT FOR
MANY YEARS AND A LOT OF HER
STUDENTS CALLED AND SAID, OH, MY
GOD, THAT IS YOU.
SO I STOLE IT FROM MY MOM RIGHT
AND LEFT.
THAT TOUGH COOKIE, THAT'S WHO
SHE WAS AT WORK THEN AT HOME SHE
WAS A KITTEN.
>> I LIKE THAT.
I LIKE THAT.
IT'S INTERESTING BECAUSE THIS
SEASON EVERY SHOW, EACH WEEK IS
DONE FROM THE PERSPECTIVE OF ONE
OF THE CHARACTERS.
THIS WEEK IT'S YOUR CHARACTER
CHARLOTTE ON BED REST WITH
TRIPLETS.
>> RIGHT.
>> WE'LL SHOW YOU A CLIP TO
THAT.
CHECK IT OUT.
>> HAVE YOU LIKED YOUR JOB.
>> IS THIS A TRICK QUESTION?
>> NO.
>> THEN YES, I MEAN I KNOW SOME
PEOPLE THINK NURSES ARE JUST
FRUSTRATED DOCTORS BUT I LIKE
BEING MORE HANDS ON.
>> I'M MAKING YOU MY PRIVATE
NURSE.
NO ONE ELSE HERE KNOWS THEIR ASS
FROM THE FLOOR IN THE GROUND.
>> I'M THE FLOOR MANAGER.
I CAN'T CATER TO ONE PERSON.
>> YOU CAN.
FIGURE IT OUT.
>> THAT PREGNANCY WAS THE
LARGEST BELLY AND THAT THING --
I HAVE SUCH COMPASSION FOR ANY
WOMAN WHO'S CARRIED ANY CHILD
BUT MULTIPLES.
HONESTLY, I MEAN IT'S NOT VERY
LADYLIKE BUT I'LL JUST OUT IT.
WHEN I HAD TO GO TO THE
BATHROOM, THE STALL COULD NOT
HOLD ME.
I MEAN IT WAS JUST MASSIVE.
SO I MEAN I HAVE A NEW PLACE IN
MY HEART FOR PREGNANCY.
>> THIS IS A QUOTE.
YOU HAVEN'T LIVED UNTIL YOU'VE
WORN A TRIPLE PREGNANCY BELLY.
>> YEP.
>> WHAT ELSE DID YOU LEARN FROM
THAT?
>> WOW.
>> WOULD YOU LIKE TO EVER BE
PREGNANT WITH TRIPLETS?
>> ARE YOU KIDDING ME.
I WOULD BE HAPPY WITH WHATEVER
CAME INTO MY LIFE, CERTAINLY I
WOULDN'T BE RESISTANT BUT I
WOULD NEVER AGO FOR THAT.
I DON'T KNOW WHY ANYONE WOULD.
THAT PICTURE YOU SAW WAS A
PICTURE I TOOK IN MY TRAILER.
I WAS LAYING DOWN AND SENT IT TO
SHONDA AND TO MY HUSBAND IN
PREPARATION FOR WHEN I ACTUALLY
AM PREGNANT.
IT WON'T BE QUITE AS HARROWING
FOR HIM TO SEE ME GET ENORMOUS.
>> YOU DID A LOT OF DIFFERENT
DANCE STYLE, TANGO, HIP-HOP,
BALLROOM.
DID YOU HAVE PRIOR DANCE
EXPERIENCE.
>> THE FUNNY THING, WE GOT A
SCRIPT AND PAUL AND I WEREN'T
ASKED -- GOOD LORD MUCH THE
HIP-HOP IS HYSTERICAL.
WE WEREN'T ASKED IF WE COULD
DANCE.
WE DABBLED BECAUSE ANY ACTOR
WHO'S BEEN TRAINED HAS HAD A FEW
LESSONS BUT I HAVE NO IDEA --
THE TANGO IN FIVE REHEARSALS.
THAT'S WHAT WE GOT, FUNNY.
>> HE LOOKS GREAT.
>> HE WAS HILARIOUS.
>> WE LOVE LISTENING TO THE
SOUTHERN ACCENT AND YOU'RE FROM
GEORGIA.
>> I AM.
>> AND YOU GREW UP, IT SAYS, ON
A TOBACCO FARM.
YOU DROVE A TRACTOR AND YOU
LIVED IN AN AREA WITH ONE
TRAFFIC LIGHT.
TAKE US BACK TO THAT TIME.
WHAT WAS THE CHIDEHIDE LIKE.
>> THE CHILDHOOD WAS INCREDIBLE.
A TIME WHEN CHILDREN COULD
ACTUALLY WALK AROUND BY
THEMSELVES AND BE KIDS AND PLAY
AND, YOU KNOW, HAVE A COMBHUPTS
IN THAT WAY SO I'M VERY GRATEFUL
FOR THAT BUT ALSO MY PARPS HAD
HAD ME WORKING ON A FARM AT THE
AGE OF 8.
WHEN YOU START --
>> WERE YOU DRIVING THE TRACTOR.
>> AT 8.
IT WAS VERY ILLEGAL.
BUT I -- I WAS PROBABLY A BETTER
DRIVER THAN MOST BY THE TIME I
WAS 16 AS A RESULT OF THAT.
BUT WE DID IT OLD SCHOOL AND
PICKED TOBACCO.
THERE WAS NO HIGH-TECH COMMIT.
IT WAS ON FOOT AND BY HAND.
NO AMOUNT OF GETTING UP AT 5:00
IN THE MORNING FOR HAIR AND
MAKEUP WAS AS EVER HARD AS
GETTING UP AT 5:00 AND GOING IN
THE FIELD.
>> THANK YOU, KADEE FOR PUTTING
A SMILE ON OUR FACES.
OUR THANKS TO KADEE STRICKLAND.
"PRIVATE PRACTICE" AIRS TUESDAY
NIGHTS AT 10:00 P.M. ON ABC AND
SEASONS ONE THROUGH FIVE ARE
AVAILABLE ON DVD.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
WE LOVE KADEE.
[ APPLAUSE ]
[ Male Announcer ]
PLAYING IN THE NFL IS TOUGH.
♪
DOING IT WITH A COLD,
JUST NOT GOING TO HAPPEN.
VICKS DAYQUIL --
POWERFUL NON-DROWSY
6-SYMPTOM COLD & FLU RELIEF.
♪
NO MATTER WHAT CITY
YOU'RE PLAYING TOMORROW.
[ coughs ]
[ Male Announcer ] YOU CAN'T
LET A COLD KEEP YOU UP TONIGHT.
♪
VICKS NYQUIL --
POWERFUL NIGHTTIME
6-SYMPTOM COLD & FLU RELIEF.
♪
Cheese plate?
Cheese plate...nope.
I made something better.
♪
You used the oven?
BOOM
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
Pillsbury Crescents.
Let the making begin.
♪
There's a place where the
sky is always blue
and the kids always eat their
vegetables.
Because the salad there is
always  served
with the
Original Hidden Valley Ranch.
It's the way Ranch is supposed
to taste.
And try Italians and
Vinaigrettes from Hidden Valley.
Your soups are
so awesomely delicious
my husband and I
can't stop eating 'em!
What's...that...
on your head?
Can curlers!
Tomato Basil,
Potato with bacon...
we've got a lot of empty cans.
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
TO SAY GET WELL
TO YOUR LOVED ONES.
THIS CAME FOR YOU, MOMMY.
[ Female Announcer ] BUT WHEN
YOU SEND A KLEENEX® CARE PACK,
COMPLETE WITH AMERICA'S
SOFTEST TISSUE,
YOU'RE ALSO GIVING
A WARM GESTURE OF CARE.
KLEENEX®.
AMERICA'S SOFTEST TISSUE.
RED JARS ARE ALL THE SAME RIGHT?
WRONG!
YOU NEED THREE USES
OF A $15 CREAM
TO EQUAL THE MOISTURIZING POWER
OF ONE USE OF REGENERIST
MICROSCULPTING CREAM.
SEEMS NOT ALL RED JARS
ARE CREATED EQUAL.
OLAY REGENERIST.
SEEMS NOT ALL RED JARS
ARE CREATED EQUAL.
TO FLAT SCREENS...NS...
TWIZZLERIZE YOUR
ENTERTAINMENT EVERYDAY
WITH TWIZZLERS,
THE TWIST YOU CAN'T RESIST.
[ Female Announcer ]
ONE DROP OF ULTRA DAWN
HAS TWICE THE EVERYDAY
GREASE CLEANING INGREDIENTS
OF ONE DROP OF THE LEADING
NON-CONCENTRATED BRAND...
TO CLEAN 2X MORE GREASY DISHES.
DAWN DOES MORE.
SO IT'S NOT A CHORE.
SO YOU THINK
SANTA WILL LIKE THESE...
RED AND GREEN M&M'S?
I DON'T KNOW!
I NEVER MET THE GUY!
WHAAAAA!
HE DOES EXIST!
THEY DO EXIST!
UHM... SANTA?
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> WE WERE ON A BREAK AND DR.
WELNER WAS CONTINUING TO TELL
OUR AUDIENCE.
HE SAID, IF YOU'RE SEEING
SOMEONE WHO IS STARTING TO
DISCONNECT OR SEEMS ISOLATED,
THERE ARE SIMPLE ACTS OF
KINDNESS, LOVE THEM BECAUSE YOU
CAN BREAK THROUGH.
>> HUMANIZE THEM.
>> LOVE ON THEM, SIMPLE ACTS OF
KINDNESS.
>> SOME OF THE FUNERALS ARE
STARTING TODAY SO WE JUST HAVE
TO SAY AGAIN, YOU KNOW, WE'RE
JUST FIVE PEOPLE HERE BUT OUR
THOUGHTS ARE LOVE, OUR PRAYERS
ARE WITH EVERY MEMBER OF THOSE
FAMILIES.
SO --
>> WELL SAID.
WE WANT EVERYONE TO HAVE A GREAT
TIME.
TAKE A LITTLE TIME TO ENJOY "THE
VIEW."
[ APPLAUSE ]
>>> NEXT ON "ABC 7 NEWS," THE
LATEST ON THE SCHOOL TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE
GUNMAN AND SCHOOL NURSE STORY OF
SURVIVAL.
>> AND AS STUDENT RETURN TO
CLASSROOM.
HOW THE BAY AREA IS REACTING.
>> AND NATIONAL DEBATE OVER GUN
CONTROL.
NEW POLLS SHOWING
>>> FOLLOWING THE VICTIMS OF THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL TRAGEDY.
>> THE VERY FIRST FUNERALS ARE
UNDERWAY RIGHT NOW.
PEOPLE GATHERED TO REMEMBER TWO
OF THE 20 YOUNG STUDENTS KILLED