AUTHORITIES HAVE IDENTIFIED ALL
OF THE VICTIMS.
THERE ARE 27 OF THEM.
20 ARE CHILDREN.
THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER AND THE
PRINCIPAL ARE AMONG THE ADULTS
WHO WERE KILLED.
TOMAS IS LIVE WHERE WE HEARD AN
UPDATE.
>> GOOD MORNING, A SHORT TIME
AGO A TRUCK FULL OF FLOWERS
ARRIVED AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AS THE COMMUNITY BEGINS
TO COPE WITH THE UNIMAGINABLE
HORROR OF STUDENTS LOST AT
SCHOOL.
>> IT ALL STARTED ON AN ORDINARY
DAY IN UNLIKELY PLACES.
A SLEEPY NEW ENGLAND DOWN, ONE
OF THE WORST MASS SHOOTINGS IN
THIS NATION'S HISTORY.
>> AUTHORITIES SAY 20-YEAR-OLD
ADAM LANZA HEADED TO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL ARMED WITH A
SEMI-AUTOMATIC ASSAULT RIFLE AND
TWO HIGH POWERED PISTOLS.
AUTHORITIES HAVE RECOVERED MORE
THAN THREE WEAPONS.
>> HE WAS NOT VOLUNTARILY LED
INTO THE SCHOOL BUT FORCED HIS
WAY INTO THE SCHOOL.
>> HOURS BEFORE POLICE SAY LANZA
HAD SHOT HIS MOTHER AT HER HOME
AND HEADED TO THE SCHOOL WHERE
HE KILLED 26 PEOPLE MOSTLY
CHILDREN AND HIMSELF.
AFTER THE RAMPAGE ENDED,
TEACHERS LED THE STUDENTS SINGLE
FIRE TO A NEARBY FIRE STATION.
>> WE HAD TO CLOSE OUR EYES AND
PUT OUR HANDS ON OTHER PEOPLE'S
SHOULDERS AND THEN OUR TEACHER
HELD THE FIRST PERSON'S HAND AND
LED US OUT.
>> FRANTIC PARENTS ARRIVED AT
THE SCHOOL SIMPLY HOPING TO FIND
THEIR CHILDREN ALIVE.
AUTHORITIES ARE STILL SEARCHING
FOR ANSWERS.
THEY ARE ALSO QUESTIONS HIS
BROTHER AND FATHER TRYING TO
DETERMINE WHAT LED TO THE
KILLING SPREE.
RESIDENTS OF NEWTOWN SAYS THE
HORROR STILL DOESN'T SEEM REAL.
>> TO SEE IF IT IS REALLY REAL,
IT'S A NIGHTMARE.
>> Reporter: AUTHORITIES SAY
THEY HAVE DISCOVERED EVIDENCE
THAT HELPS EXPLAIN HOW AND WHY
THIS HAPPENED BUT THEY WILL BE
WORKING THE SCENE FOR AT LEAST
ANOTHER DAY OR TWO.
>> Katie: AS WE MENTIONED
AUTHORITIES RELEASED NEW
INFORMATION, THE SHOOTER, ADAM
LANZA FORCED HIS WAY INTO THE
BUILDING.
POLICE SAY HE WAS NOT
VOLUNTARILY LED INTO THE SCHOOL.
HE GAINED ACCESS TO THE SCHOOL
BY BREAKING A GLASS WINDOW NEAR
THE FRONT DOOR.
HE BROUGHT THREE GUNS INTO THE
SCHOOL AND THE WEAPONS ARE
REGISTERED TO HIS MOTHER.
>>> HAPPENING NOW IN SAN
FRANCISCO, SMALL GROUPS OF
PEOPLE ARE GATHERING TO REMEMBER
THE VICTIMS.
>> JUST A FEW PEOPLE HAVE SHOWN
UP SO FAR.
THEY ARE GATHERING IN THE
MEMORIAL GROVE BEHIND ME.
IT'S A GROUP LED BY FAITH GROUP.
THE ORGANIZER SAID THEY DECIDED
TO HOLD THE VIGIL REGARDLESS OF
RELIGION, PEOPLE NEED TO BE ABLE
TO FIND A PLACE TO COME
TOGETHER.
YOU HONOR THE VICTIMS BUT ALSO
TO REMEMBER THE GOOD.
WE WILL HAVE THAT INTERVIEW WITH
HER COMING UP IN ABOUT 30
MINUTES.
WHAT YOU ARE SEEING NOW IS VIDEO
FROM A CANDLELIGHT VIGIL LAST
NIGHT IN WALNUT CREEK WHERE TWO
DOZEN GATHERED AND LIKE SO MANY
VIGILS, THIS ONE CAME TOGETHER
FAIRLY QUICKLY AFTER THE
TRAGEDY.
SHE WAS COMPELLED TO DO IS
SOMETHING WHILE WATCHING THE
NEWS AS THE HORROR UNFOLDED
THROUGHOUT THE DAY.
>> SOMETHING LIKE THIS, OUR
HEARTS ARE BROKEN BUT WHEN WE
GATHER HERE LIKE THIS, IT SHOWS
OUR SPIRITS ARE NOT BROKEN.
>> PARENTS BROUGHT THEIR SCHOOL
AGED CHILDREN AND EXPLAINED WHAT
HAPPENED IN HOPES OF GETTING
THEIR CHILDREN TO UNDERSTAND
WHAT THEIR FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT ARE GOING THROUGH
RIGHT NOW.
BACK HERE IN GOLDEN GATE PARK
THE PUBLIC IS WELCOME AT THIS
VIGIL.
THEY ARE EXPECTING ANYWHERE FROM
TEN TO 80 PEOPLE.
YOU CAN COME AND OFFER PRAYERS,
WRITE LETTERS AND REMEMBER THOSE
SWEET YOUNG AND OLD VICTIMS.
>> Katie: MASS SHOOTING HAS BEEN
EMOTIONAL FOR PARENTS.
THE DEAN OF THE SCHOOL AND
EDUCATION OF PSYCHOLOGY TELLS
ABC NEWS YOU FIRST NEED TO
CONFRONT YOUR OWN FEELINGS,
WHETHER THOSE INCLUDE FEAR AND
ANXIETY AND SPEAK TO YOUR CHILD
CALMLY AND LISTEN INTENTLY.
THE TIME TO DO IT IS NOW.
>> I WOULD TALK TODAY.
I DON'T THINK IT IS WORTH
WAITING UNTIL THE END OF THE
WEEKEND OR WAITING UNTIL A
BRIGHT MOMENT.
THE KIDS ARE EXPERIENCING THIS.
THEY HAVE TO UNDERSTAND WHAT
DOES THIS REALLY MEAN WHEN AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HAS THIS KIND
OF TRAGEDY.
>> THE DOCTOR SAYS YOU SHOULD
REASSURE YOUR KIDS THEY ARE SAFE
IN SCHOOL.
WE HAVE A LOT MORE COMING AS THE
TRAGEDY UNFOLDS.
STAY WITH US FOR CONTINUING
COVERAGE.
YOU CAN RECEIVE UPDATES ON YOUR
SMART PHONE BY DOWNLOADING OUR
FREE NEWS APP.
SIGN UP TO GET THE LATEST
INFORMATION AT ABC7NEWS.COM.
WE'RE UPDATING OUR FACEBOOK PAGE
NEWS AND AT TWITTER.
LET'S GET OUR FIRST LOOK AT THE
WEATHER.
>> GOOD MORNING.
THIS IS A LIVE LOOK AT OUR HD
EMERYVILLE CAMERA.
WE DO HAVE SUNSHINE AROUND THE
BAY.
ENJOY IT WHILE WE HAVE IT
BECAUSE THE CLOUDS WILL BE
THICKENING.
IT'S A LITTLE CHILLY OUT THERE
ALL ACROSS THE BAY AREA.
WE ARE STILL BELOW FREEZING BUT
WE HAVE THIS COMING OUR WAY.
IT'S RAIN DEVELOPING THROUGHOUT
THE BAY AREA.
IT'S GOING TO TAKE TIME TO GET
HERE BUT WE WILL LOOK FOR LIGHT
AMOUNTS OF RAIN THROUGHOUT THE
DAY.
ALTHOUGH IT SHOULD BE IN THE
NORTH BAY AS SOON AS 11:00.
STARTING OUT WITH NUMBERS BELOW
FREEZING AND FOG WITH LOW TO MID
40s AROUND THE BAY.
BY THE AFTERNOON, ONLY UPPER 40s
WITH LOW SNOW LEVELS IN THE
NORTH BAY, TO THE LOWER 50s
AROUND THE BAY.
SHOWERING LINGERING TO THE
EVENING HOURS.
WHAT ABOUT THE REST OF THE
WEEKEND, LAST WEEK BEFORE WINTER
BEGINS, I'LL HAVE THE FORECAST
FOR YOU COMING UP.
>> OUR COVERAGE OF THE DEADLY
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SHOOTING
CONTINUES.
UP NEXT, YOU'LL HEAR TWO YOUNG
BROTHERS DESCRIBE THE DAY.
WE'LL HAVE MORE ON THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT IN JUST A
MOMENT.
HA HAVING?
FIRST I WILL HAVE
THE SHIRE SKILLET.
NEXT I SHALL PROCURE
SOME HOBBIT HOLES
WITH A SIDE OF THE
PUMPKIN PANCAKES.
THAT OUGHT TO HOLD ME
TILL SECOND BREAKFAST.
EAT LIKE A HOBBIT.
ONLY AT DENNY'S.
AND SEE "THE HOBBIT:
AN UNEXPECTED JOURNEY."
So I get Claritin Clear...
...for strong, non-drowsy
relief of all my allergies...
...like dust...
...mold...
...pets...
...and pollen.
Looks good.
Thanks.
I Live Claritin Clear.
>>> WHEN WE HEARD GUNSHOTS, IT
DIDN'T SOUND LIKE ARMY GUNSHOTS
AND POLICEMAN GUNSHOTS, WE WERE
HIDING IN MY TEACHER'S OFFICE.
IT WAS SCARY.
WE HAD TO HIDE THERE BECAUSE WE
WERE REALLY NEAR THAT GUY.
THA THE GUY COULD HAVE COME INTO
THE DOOR.
>> EVERYTHING WAS FINE AND
NORMAL, FRIDAY MORNING WOULD BE
AND THEN IT ALL CHANGED.
>> Katie: THAT IS HOW BROTHERS,
FOURTH GRADE STUDENTS, DESCRIBE
THE CHAOS AS SOON AS SHOTS WERE
FIRED.
WE HAVE LIVE CONTINUING COVERAGE
ON CONNECTICUT AND ONLINE AT
ABC7NEWS.COM.
AN INVESTIGATION IS UNDER WAY
AFTER AN OFF-DUTY CHP OFFICER
WAS KILLED IN A HEAD-ON IN
FAIRFIELD.
IT HAPPENED JUST BEFORE 6:00 ON
ON HIGHWAY 12 NEAR RED TOP ROAD
LAST NIGHT.
THE OFFICER WAS ON HIS PERSONAL
MOTORCYCLE WHEN HE HIT A PICKUP
TRUCK THAT WAS TURNING LEFT.
THE OFFICER WAS THROWN AND HIT
BY THE HONDA.
UNIDENTIFIED OFFICER WAS
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCENE.
>> AN 82-YEAR-OLD IS FACING
FELONY CHARGES OF VEHICULAR
MANSLAUGHTER AFTER HE WAS
INVOLVED IN A TERRIFYING CRASH
ON INTERSTATE 280 IN SAN MATEO
COUNTY.
THEY SAY THE MAN WAS SPEEDING
WHEN HIS CAR VEERED ON TO THE
MEDIAN.
>> WE WERE OVER THE SCENE JUST
MINUTES AFTER A CRASH AT I-280
AND EDGEWOOD ROAD.
THE DRIVER HAD PULLED NEXT TO
THE MEDIAN TO FIX A FLAT TIRE.
IT WAS THEN THIS BLACK
VOLKSWAGEN CRASHED INTO THE
LEXUS.
>> THERE WERE FOUR PEOPLE TOTAL.
THREE OF THE PEOPLE WERE
PRONOUNCED AT THE SCENE.
>> A WOMAN WAS KILLED AND
28-YEAR-OLD MAN AND 28-YEAR-OLD
WOMAN.
IT WASN'T CLEAR WHO WAS IN AND
OUTSIDE OF THE CAR.
EXTENT OF THE DAMAGE AND FORCE
OF THE IMPACT ARE IMPORTANT
CLUES.
>> IT LOOKS LIKE SPEED WAS A
FACTOR.
>> WE HAVE LEARNED THAT THE
DRIVER OF THIS BLACK VOLKSWAGEN
IS AN 28-YEAR-OLD MAN FROM THE
BAY AREA.
HE WAS TAKEN TO STANFORD MEDICAL
CENTER.
ONCE SHE REHIGH SCHOOLED HE WILL
FACE FELONY VEHICULAR
MANSLAUGHTER CHARGES.
IT CAUSED A TRAFFIC BACK-UP FOR
MILES.
INVESTIGATORS SAY NEITHER
ALCOHOL NOR DRUGS APPEAR TO BE A
FACTOR BUT STRESS THEY ARE IN
THE PRELIMINARY STAGES OF THEIR
INVESTIGATION.
>>> AND LISA ARGEN IS HERE WITH
A LOOK AT THE FORECAST.
WE NEED TO LISTEN CAREFULLY
BECAUSE THINGS ARE HAPPENING.
>> A COUPLE WEEK SYSTEMS AT THE
BEGINNING OF THE WORK WEEK AND
THEN THE RAIN WILL GET MORE
INTERESTING.
RIGHT HERE, RIGHT NOW FROM THE
ROOF CAMERA, A LITTLE BREEZY.
NUMBERS IN THE 40s STILL AROUND
FREEZING, FOG IN NORTH AND EAST
>>> IN RESPONSE TO CRITICISM.
UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA HAS
DECIDED TO NIX PLANS TO USE A
NEW LOGO.
IT SHOWS A SCENE NESTLED IN A
SHIELD BUT CAME UNDER FIRE FROM
PEOPLE THAT CALLED IT BLAND AND
NONDESCRIPT.
I WANT TO GO BACK TO THE LOGO
THEY HAVE USED FOR 144 YEARS.
>> NASA'S GRAVITY MISSION OF THE
MOON COMES TO AN END ON MONDAY.
THE SPACE AGENCY WILL
INTENTIONALLY CRASH THE PROBE
INTO A CLIFF.
THEY LAUNCHED THE GRAIL MISSION
IN SEPTEMBER OF LAST YEAR.
THEY SAY IT HAS BEEN A HUGE
SUCCESS.
BACK HERE ON EARTH, WE NEED TO
KNOW WHAT TO EXPECT.
A LITTLE BIT OF EVERYTHING.
>> IT IS STILL COLD OUT THERE.
32 DEGREES IN SANTA ROSA.
IT WAS 29 BY THE DELTA.
AS WE HEAD OUTSIDE, TAHOE VALLEY
AIRPORT JUST 1 DEGREE THERE.
SO THEY HAVE CLEAR CONDITIONS
WITH A FORECAST OF CLOUDY
CONDITIONS LATER ON TODAY WITH A
HIGH OF 33 AT SOUTH LAKE.
CLOSER TO HOME, OUR EAST BAY
CAMERA WITH TEMPERATURES JUST IN
THE LOW 40s.
YOU CAN SEE THE CLOUD COVER
HERE.
WE HAVE A LITTLE BIT OF SUNSHINE
AND WE'LL SEE MORE DRY
CONDITIONS THROUGHOUT THE
MORNING HOURS ACROSS THE BAY
BEFORE THE RAIN HEADS OUR WAY.
IT WILL BE HITTING YOU FIRST IN
THE NORTH BAY AND COLD AIR IN
PLACE AND SOME OF THE VALLEYS.
IT IS GOING TO BE HARD TO GET
OUT OF THE 40s AND LOW SNOW
LEVELS FOR LAKE COUNTY.
RAIN IS GETTING CLOSE TO
CLOVERDALE.
IT IS OFFSHORE AND IT IS LIGHTED
BUT SPREAD OVER THE BAY AREA AND
COLD AND DAMP AFTERNOON.
35 IN NAPA.
OAKLAND, 41.
36 IN REDWOOD CITY.
39, HALF MOON BAY.
INFORMATION IS, 40.
TEMPERATURES ARE CHILLY AND WITH
A LITTLE BIT OF FOG OUT THERE
THE VISIBILITY HAS BEEN POOR
FROM NOVATO TO SANTA ROSA AND
LIVERMORE.
SO BE CAREFUL.
WITH THE COLD START WE'LL LOOK
FOR THE CHILLY TEMPERATURES TO
LINGER INTO THE AFTERNOON.
RAIN DEVELOPING WITH A CHANCE OF
SHOWERS INTO YOUR SUNDAY.
TODAY LOOKS LIKE THE RAIN YES,
SIR DAY OUT OF WEEKEND WITH LESS
RAIN.
THE SYSTEM WILL HEAD OUT OF
TOWN.
SO FAR WINTER HAS NOT EVEN
ARRIVED YET OFFICIALLY.
LOOK WHERE WE ARE IN TERMS OF
OUR PERCENT OF NORMAL.
143% OF NORMAL IN DOWNTOWN SAN
FRANCISCO.
122% OF NORMAL IN SAN JOSE.
THIS FIRST SYSTEM, VERY WEAK.
WE'LL CALL IT WINDY AND WITH
THIS ANEMIC LOOKING FRONT WE
WON'T SEE MUCH IN THE WAY OF
RAINFALL THROUGHOUT THE WEEKEND.
BEST ESTIMATES WILL BE IN THE
NORTH BAY.
HERE WE ARE AT NOONTIME.
YOU WILL NOTICE THE RAIN FROM
SAN FRANCISCO TO SAN RAFAEL.
WITH THOSE COLD TEMPERATURES,
SNOW SHOULD BE COMING DOWN IN
SPOTS AROUND LAKE COUNTY.
NOT A LOT OF MOISTURE ASSOCIATED
WITH THIS SYSTEM.
AS I PUSHES THROUGH THE BAY
AREA, BY 2:00 IN THE AFTERNOON,
THAT SHOULD DO IT.
THEN WE'LL BREAK OUT INTO
SCATTERED SHOWERS RIGHT THROUGH
SUNDAY MORNING.
TAKE A LOOK.
WE'RE LOOKING AT MAINLY DRY
CONDITIONS THROUGHOUT THE
AFTERNOON UNTIL THE NEXT SYSTEM
HEADS THROUGH TOMORROW NIGHT.
TRACE THROUGH THE SOUTH BAY TO
TENTH IN THE EAST BAY.
LOOK AT THESE TEMPERATURES.
JUST MID AND UPPER 40s FOR THE
LAKE COUNTY, 52 IN WATSONVILLE.
SAN FRANCISCO COMING IN AT 52.
ONLY AT 53.
YOU'LL NOTICE A FEW SHOWERS
TOMORROW MORNING.
MONDAY MORNING'S COMMUTED LOOKS
WET.
JUST A CHANCE ON TUESDAY.
WEDNESDAY LOOKS LIKE THE DRY DAY
FRIDAY, AS WINTER BEGINS.
>>> THE N.B.A. OBSERVED THEIR
MOMENT OF SILENCE TO HONOR THOSE
SCHOOL SHOOTING VICTIMS IN
CONNECTICUT.
THIS WAS THE SCENE IN DENVER
WHERE FANS WERE ASKED TO STAND
BEFORE THE START OF THE GAME.
LARRY BEIL BEGINS OUR MORNING
SPORTS WITH THE WARRIORS AND
MAGIC.
>> GOOD MORNING.
SPORTS CLEARLY A DIVERSION AFTER
WHAT WE SAW WHAT HAPPENED IN
CONNECTICUT.
WE'LL START WITH THE WARRIORS
TRYING TO KEEP THEIR ROAD TRIP
GOING.
FIVE WINS IS THE MOST ON EAST
COAST SINCE 1962.
WELCOME TO THE BLACK PARTY.
FIRST HALF, WARRIORS WERE DOWN
16 AND GET IT OUT OF HERE.
MAGIC, 7-13 AND TWO AGAINST
GOLDEN STATE.
J.J. REDDICK, HE HAD 16.
ORLANDO UP 17.
DAVID LEE BRINGING IT.
23 POINTS, 15 REBOUNDS BUT THE
WARRIORS NEVER CLOSE THAN NINE
POINTS.
THEY DROP THEIR FIRST GAME ON
SUCCESSFUL ROAD TRIP, 99-85.
>> LAKERS TRYING TO SNAP THEIR
FOUR-GAME SKID AGAINST WIZARDS.
KOBE BRYANT, BEHIND THE BACK TO
DWIGHT HOWARD.
12 POINTS FOR HOWARD.
WIZARD FANS, THE ALLEY-OOP FROM
JORDAN CRAWFORD TO WEBSTER.
KOBE FINISHES WITH 30.
COMING DOWN THE LANE, SOMEBODY
IS GOING TO BLOCK.
102-96 BUT THEY ARE 10 AND 14.
>> DE LaSALLE GOES AGAINST
CORONA.
TWO WINS SHY OF 400 BUT HE IS
OPENLY TALKING ABOUT RETIREMENT.
THE COACH HAS LED DE LaSALLE FOR
34 YEARS.
IT'S THE ONE AND ONLY JOB HE
WANTED.
>> I WANTED TO BE A HIGH SCHOOL
TEACHER AND I WANTED TO BE AT
THIS SCHOOL.
THAT IS WHEN I WAS 24 YEARS OLD.
IT NEVER CHANGED.
NEVER ONE TO JUMP A LEVEL OR
ANYTHING LIKE THAT.
IT'S BEEN VERY REWARDING.
IT'S BEEN A GOOD CAREER.
>> HE IS AN AMAZING COACH.
49ers HEAD TO NEW ENGLAND.
IF THE NINERS WIN THEY CLINCH A
PLAYOFF SPOT.
THEY HAVE BEEN FOCUSING ON THE
QUARTERBACK SITUATION BUT DON'T
FORGET ABOUT FRANK GORE.
HE REACHED THOUSAND YARD MARK
FOR SIXTH TIME IN HIS CAREER.
GORE BANGED UP THIS SEASON BUT
HE FINDS A WAY TO BLOCK OUT
PAINT.
>> IT WAS GREAT.
A LOT OF THE CASE, THE LOVE OF
THE GAME.
IT'S HOW MUCH HE LOVES FOOTBALL.
HOW MUCH HE LIKES PRACTICING AND
PLAYING THIS GAME.
THAT HAS PLAYED A BIG PART IN
MAKING HIM SUCH A DURABLE GUY
WEEK AFTER WEEK.
>> AND RAIDERS HOST THE CHIEFS
ON SUNDAY.
HE PUTS HIS FEATHER WEIGHT TITLE
AGAINST ORISI.
HE WEIGHED IN 121 1/2.
ORISI BARELY MADE WEIGHT AT 122
POUNDS EVEN.
THAT A WRAP.
MIKE WILL BE HERE WITH ALL YOUR
HIGHLIGHTS LATER ON.
HAVE A GREAT WEEKEND.
I'M LARRY BEIL.
>>> OUR COVERAGE OF THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT
CONTINUES.
A COMMUNITY IN MOURNING TODAY AS
WE ARE LEARNING NEW INFORMATION
ABOUT THE CRIME, THE SHOOTER AND
WHAT EXACTLY HAPPENED INSIDE THE
SCHOOL.
AMID ALL OF THE TRAGEDY, LIFE
SAVING STORIES, THE TEACHERS
THAT KEPT CHILDREN SAFE AND CALM
AS THE GUNMAN OPENED FIRE IN
CLASSROOMS.
>> LIVE AT GOLDEN GATE PARK
WHERE A FEW MEMBERS OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO COMMUNITY ARE
GATHERING TO REMEMBER THE 27
VICTIMS OF THE CONNECTICUT
SHOOTING.
WE'LL BRING IT TO YOU HERE LIVE
RIGHT AFTER THE BREAK.
>> A LIVE LOOK AT SAN FRANCISCO
AT FLAG AT HALF-STAFF ON THE
EMBARCADERO OVERLOOKING THE BAY
AS ORDERED
>>> IT WAS NOT ALLOWED ENTER IF
YOU WILL.
>> NEW INFORMATION FROM
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE.
THEY SAY THE GUNMAN ADAM LANZA
FORCED HIS WAY INTO THE SCHOOL.
THERE ARE 27 VICTIMS INCLUDING
THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER, 20
CHILDREN AND SEVEN ADULTS IN
ALL.
POLICE SAY THE SHOOTER BROUGHT
THREE GUNS INTO THE SCHOOL AND
THE WEAPONS WERE REGISTERED TO
HIS MOTHER.
A COMMUNITY MOURNS AND ASKS WHY
DID THIS HAPPEN.
[ SIREN ]
>> YOU ARE CONTINUING TO HEAR
WHAT HE BELIEVES TO BE GUNFIRE.
>> THE FIRST WORDS WERE CHILLING
AND ONLY GOT WORSE.
>> THEY ARE REPORTING MULTIPLE
FATALITIES INVOLVED IN THE
SHOOTING.
>> WITH EACH NEW REPORT THE
HORROR DEEPENED.
>> THEY SAY THE NUMBER OF DEAD
CLOSER TO 30 THAN TO 20 AND
SADLY MOST OF THEM ARE CHILDREN.
>> THIS MORNING, WE KNOW THE
DEATH TOLL IS 27.
20 OF THOSE KILLED WERE CHIN.
THERE ARE STILL MANY QUESTIONS.
MOST COMMON ONE IS WHY?
>> IN THESE TIMES, TROUBLED,
UNTHINKABLE HAPPENS IN OUR VERY
MIDST OUR FAITH IS TESTED.
>> AS RESIDENTS CAME TOGETHER AT
VIGILS FRIDAY NIGHT, LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS CONTINUE
TO WORK AT THE SCENE TO PIECE
TOGETHER WHAT HAPPENED.
>> WE CONSIDER AN INVESTIGATION
TO BE MASSIVE.
NUMBER TWO IT'S LIKE A BIG
PUZZLE.
WE HAVE TO PUT ALL THE PIECES
TOGETHER AS TO HOW AND WHY THIS
OCCURRED.
>> AT THE CENTER, ADAM LANZA,
20-YEAR-OLD IDENTIFIED AS THE
SHOOTER.
HE HAD NO KNOWN CRIMINAL RECORD
BEFORE ENTERING THE SCHOOL ON
FRIDAY MORNING.
HE WAS FOUND DEAD IN A CLASSROOM
APPARENTLY BY HIS OWN HAND.
A FORMER CLASSMATE THAT KNEW HIM
DESCRIBED HIM AS QUIET.
>> HE WAS A LITTLE BIT
DIFFERENT.
HE MOSTLY STUCK TO HIMSELF, BUT
I DON'T KNOW YOU COULD HAVE
PREDICTED THIS.
>> THE VICTIMS ARE BEING MOURNED
ACROSS THE NATION AT THIS
CANDLELIGHT VIGIL AT U.S.
CAPITOL BUT NOWHERE IS SADNESS
MORE THAN IN THIS SMALL
COMMUNITY.
>> HE REALLY STRUGGLED TO FIND
THE WORDS AS TO WHAT HAPPENED.
>> EVEN AN EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT
OBAMA HAD TO FIGHT BACK TEARS.
>> THIS EVENING MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO I KNOW WHAT EVERY PARENT
WILL DO IN AMERICA IS HUG OUR
CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER AND
TELL THEM THAT WE LOVE THEM AND
REMIND EACH OTHER HOW MUCH WE
LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT THAT CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT.
>> ONE OF THE SIX ADULTS KILLED
WAS 47-YEAR-OLD, THE SCHOOL'S
PRINCIPAL.
SHE WAS KNOWN FOR HER PLAYFUL
PASSION AND JUST A MONTH AGO SHE
DRESSED UP AS A SANDY HOOK BOOK
FAIRY WEARING A CROWN TO INSPIRE
FIRST GRADERS TO READ.
>> WE'RE LEARNING ABOUT THE
BRAVE TEACHERS WHO DESPERATELY
TRIED TO PROTECT YOUNG STUDENTS
FROM THE GUNMAN.
POLICE S.W.A.T. TEAMS TRIED TO
FIND THE SHOOTER.
A FIRST GREAT TEACHER WAS KILLED
IN THE ATTACK.
SHE PUT HERSELF BETWEEN THE
SHOOTER AND CHILDREN.
"GOOD MORNING AMERICA" GEORGE
STEPHANOPOLOUS TALKED WITH HER
COUSIN WHO LEARNED OF HER LAST
ACTED.
>> MY COUSIN VICKY, TOOK THE
STUDENTS AND SHIELDED THE
CHILDREN IN THE CLOSET TRYING TO
PROTECT THEM IN BETWEEN THE
GUNMAN AND KIDS.
YES, SHE IS A HERO.
HER LIFE DREAM WAS TO BE A
TEACHER.
HER INSTINCTS KICKED IN AND
PROTECTED THE CHILDREN FROM THE
HARM THAT WAS COMING.
I'M SURE SHE HEARD WHAT WAS
GOING ON AND WENT INTO LOCKDOWN
MODE.
TOOK HER KIDS AND PUT THEM IN A
CLOSET.
BY DOING SO SHE LOST HER LIFE
PROTECTING THE LITTLE ONES.
>> THE BRAVE TEACHERS AND SCHOOL
STAFF HELPED STUDENTS.
JOSH ELLIOTT HAS MORE FROM
NEWTOWN.
>> AMID THE ANGUISH AND TRAGEDY
AND AGONY OF THE SHOOTING AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY, THERE IS
INCREDIBLE ACTS OF HEROISM.
>> I THOUGHT WE ALL WERE GOING
TO DIE.
>> SHE SAID THAT SHE LOCKED THE
CLASS OF 15 IN A TINY BATHROOM.
>> I SAID WE HAVE TO BE VERY
QUIET.
WE NEED TO WAIT FOR THE GOOD
GUYS.
>> DOWN THE HALL, STUDENTS IN
THE THIRD GRADE CLASS, FIRST
HEARD THE GUNSHOTS OVER THE
SCHOOL'S INTERCOM.
>> SHE LOCKED THE DOOR AND PUT A
PIECE OF TAPE OVER THE WINDOW OF
THE DOOR.
THEN SHE TOLD US TO GO IN THE
CORNER.
>> PREGNANT AND DUE WITH THE
BABY ANY DIE, SHE TRIED TO KEEP
HER CLASS CALM.
>> WE KEPT HEARING GUN NOISES.
JUST KEPT HEARING THAT.
>> WHAT IS SHE SAYING TO YOU?
>> SHE IS SAYING IT'S GOING TO
BE OKAY.
>> WHAT YOUR FRIENDS AND
CLASSMATES DOING AT THIS POINT?
>> WE WERE IN THE CORNER AND
THEY WERE WIDE OPEN WATCHING
EVERYTHING.
>> DID YOU HEAR YOUR PRINCIPAL
SCREAM?
>> YES, SHE WAS CRYING.
I THOUGHT SHE WAS SCREAMING.
THAT IS WHAT WE HEARD OVER THE
LOUD SPEAKER.
WE HEARD KIDS CRYING.
>> PARENTS RUSHED TO THE SCHOOL
DESPERATE TO FIND THEIR
CHILDREN.
>> AS A PARENT WHAT MUST HAVE
BEEN THOSE MOMENTS LIKE?
>> IT'S HORRIFYING.
YOU ALWAYS WORRY ABOUT YOUR KIDS
BUT IT IS SOMETHING YOU CAN
NEVER THINK IT WILL ACTUALLY
EVER HAPPEN.
YOU NEVER ARE REALLY PREPARED.
>> DO YOU WORRY ABOUT GOING BACK
TO SCHOOL?
>> YEAH, I DO.
>> WHAT DO YOU WANT TO SAY TO
HER?
>> I WANTED TO SAY THANK YOU FOR
SAVING MY LIFE AND SHE SAVED ALL
OF US.
>> WE SPOKE TO PARENTS AS THEY
RUSHED TO GET THEIR CHILDREN
OUT.
>> WHAT DO YOU REMEMBER?
WHAT HAPPENED?
>> WE GOT TO SCHOOL.
EVERYTHING WE NEEDED TO AND THEN
THEY HEARD THIS RACKET.
WE WERE LIKE ALL SCARED.
THEN WE HEARD THEM SAY.
>> EVERYBODY WENT TO THEIR
CUBBIES DID YOU HEAR MORE BAD
NOISES?
>> YEAH.
>> WHILE IT WAS GOING ON YOUR
TEACHER WAS READING YOU CALM.
YOU LOVE YOUR TEACHER YEWH.
>> DID SHE SEEM NERVOUS?
>> NO.
>> SHE JUST KEPT HER CALM AND
TOLD YOU A STORY?
>> YES.
>> DO YOU REMEMBER WHICH ONE?
>> SHE READ THE NUTCRACKER AND
ANOTHER BOOK.
THAT WAS ABOUT CHRISTMAS.
>> I LOVE THE NUTCRACKER.
DO YOU LOVE IT?
>> YES.
>> I AM AFRAID OF THE MOUSE
KING.
IT'S NOT JUST ME.
SO YOU ARE IN THERE.
HOW DO YOU LEAVE THE CLASSROOM?
>> WE GOT IN LINE AND WE HAD TO
CLOSE OUR EYES.
>> YOU HAD TO CLOSE YOUR EYES?
>> YES.
>> WHEN YOU OPENED THEM, WHERE
WERE YOU?
>> WE WERE WALKING DOWN TO THE
FIRE STATION.
>> WHAT HAPPENED AND THEN IT'S
OVER AND YOU HAVE TO BE HAPPY
YOU ARE OKAY.
ARE YOU OKAY?
>> YES.
>> DID YOU HAVE PETE THERE?
>> NO.
>> YOU KNOW YOU ARE MISSING ALL
THE PIZZA.
CHRISTMAS LIST MADE AND SENT TO
SANTA.
HOW LONG IS THE LIST?
>> THREE PIECES OF PAPER.
>>> HERE IS THE BAY AREA, GROUPS
OF PEOPLE ARE CREATING VIGILS TO
REMEMBER THE VICTIMS.
LIVE IN GOLDEN GATE PARK WHERE
ONE IS UNDER WAY RIGHT NOW.
HAS IT BEGUN?
>> JUST A FEW MOMENTS AGO, DEEP
IN THIS GROVE BEHIND US AT AIDS
MEMORIAL GROVE, A FEW PEOPLE
GATHERING.
AN EVENT PUT ON BY A GROUP, THEY
SAY IT'S IMPORTANT TIME TO COME
TOGETHER REGARDLESS OF THEIR
RELIGION.
THEY DO POP-UP EVENTS AND THIS
IS ONE OF THEM.
THEY ARE PRAYING AND WRITING
LETTERS AND REMEMBER THE
VICTIMS.
JENNIFER DECIDED TO HOLD THE
VIGIL THIS MORNING BECAUSE SHE
SAYS IT IS IMPORTANT TO SUPPORT
ONE ANOTHER REGARDLESS OF
RELIGION AND REMEMBER THE GOOD
IN OUR COMMUNITY.
>> JUST PRACTICE WITH EACH OTHER
COME TOGETHER AS A COMMUNITY.
BE REMINDED THERE ARE PEOPLE
THAT WANT TO HELP AND REACH OUT
AND WANT TO CONNECT WITH EACH
OTHER.
>> AND THIS SMALL GATHERING
ISN'T THE FIRST.
THIS IS VIDEO FROM LAST NIGHT IN
MILL VALLEY WHERE 20 PEOPLE
GATHERED TO HONOR THOSE THAT
DIED AND TO SUPPORT THE
SURVIVORS AND FIND COMFORT IN
ONE ANOTHER.
PEOPLE OF ALL AGES CONSULT ONE
ANOTHER AND REMEMBER THE 27
PEOPLE LOST.
ONE HIGH SCHOOL SOPHOMORE TOLD
"ABC 7 NEWS" SHE FELT A PERSONAL
CONNECTION TO THE TRAGEDY.
>> I FELT THAT I HAVE A YOUNGER
SISTER.
IT COULD HAVE BEEN HER.
ANYONE GOING THROUGH THAT LOSS
IS SO SAD.
I HOPE IT NEVER HAPPENS AGAIN.
I HOPE NO ONE HAS TO LOSE A
FAMILY MEMBER TO SOMETHING LIKE
THAT.
>> ACROSS THE BAY THERE WAS A
VILLAGE NIL WALNUT CREEK.
WE DO ANTICIPATE THEY WILL
CONTINUE THROUGHOUT THE WEEKEND
AS PEOPLE REACH OUT SHOW THEIR
SUPPORT AND LOVE FOR ALL THOSE
HURTING.
IF YOU WOULD LIKE TO
PARTICIPATE.
IT IS GOING ON AT AIDS MEMORIAL
GROVE AND YOU CAN PRAY AND WRITE
LETTERS.
>>> SCHOOL OFFICIALS WERE
FIELDING CALLS FROM CONCERNED
PARENTS.
A FEW PARENTS TOOK THEIR KIDS
HOME YESTERDAY.
MANY SCHOOL DISTRICTS SENT A
LETTER HOME TO REASSURE PARENTS
THEIR CHILDREN ARE SAFE AT
SCHOOL.
>> Reporter: AS NEWS SPREAD, SO
DID A SENSE OF INSECURITY IN
SCHOOLS ACROSS THE BAY AREA.
>> IT JUST REMIND NEED TO
APPRECIATE WHAT I HAVE, TO DRAW
MY LOVED ONES CLOSER.
>> CITY POLICE OFFICERS WERE
AVAILABLE FOR ANY SCHOOL TO
OFFER SAFETY ADVICE AND SENSE OF
REASSURANCE.
>> THEY ARE NOT EVEN ADULTS YET
AND THEY ARE KILLING LITTLE
KIDS.
>> IN UNION CITY THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT WILL HAVE THE FIRST
ACTIVE SCHOOL DRILL NEXT MARCH
AND THEY ARE KEENLY AWARE.
>> WITH YOUNGER CHILDREN, IT'S
LIKE A FIRE DRILL MANEUVER WHERE
YOU ARE REASSURING THE CHILDREN
AND MOVING THEM AROUND.
>> THEY WERE COACHING FACULTY
MEMBERS OF HOW TO SPOT SIGNS OF
DISTRESS IN KIDS.
>> LET THEM KNOW, THESE THINGS
DO HAPPEN.
IT RARELY HAPPENS AND THERE ARE
ADULTS THEY CAN GO TO WHEN THEY
ARE FEELING AFRAID.
>> IN SAN FRANCISCO IT WAS JUST
GUT CHECK TIME.
SCHOOL OFFICIALS WERE
REEXAMINING SAFETY PLANS SINCE
COLUMBINE.
SINCE THEN, POLICE SAY THEIR
TACTICS HAVE CHANGED.
>> WE TAKE IMMEDIATE ACTION.
WE KNOW THAT LIVES ARE AT STAKE.
IF THERE IS AN IMMEDIATE PRO
PROBLEM, OUR OFFICERS ARE TOLD
TO GATHER AND ENGAGE.
>> THIS MORNING, PRESIDENT OBAMA
IS USING HIS WEEKLY ADDRESS TO
ASK ALL AMERICANS TO KEEP THE
VICTIMS OF VIOLENCE IN MIND.
>> AS A NATION, WE HAVE ENDURED
FAR TOO MANY OF THESE TRAGEDIES
IN THE LAST FEW YEARS.
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
A SHOPPING MALL IN OREGON, A
HOUSE OF WORSHIP IN WISCONSIN, A
MOVIE THEATER IN COLORADO,
COUNTLESS STREET CORNERS AND
PLACES LIKE CHICAGO AND
PHILADELPHIA, ANY OF THESE
NEIGHBORHOODS COULD BE OUR OWN.
WE HAVE TO COME TOGETHER AND
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO TAKE
MEANINGFUL ACTION TO PREVENT
MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS FROM
HAPPENING.
>> THE PRESIDENT ASKED EACH
AMERICAN TO EXTEND A HAND TO
FAMILIES IN THEIR OWN
COMMUNITIES.
>> AS DEVELOPMENTS CONTINUE TO
UNFOLD IN CONNECTICUT, RECEIVE
URGENT UPDATES BY DOWNLOADING AN
APP.
WE ARE CONSTANTLY UPDATING THE
SCHOOL TRAGEDY ON OUR TWITTER
FEED, AS WELL.
ALSO "ABC 7 NEWS" WEB TEAM IS
SENDING OUT UPDATES.
SIGN UP FOR A BREAKING
NEWSLETTER AT ABC7NEWS.COM.
UP NEXT, NEW CALLS FOR GUN
CONTROL AS PEOPLE STRUGGLE FOR
THE TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT.
PEOPLE ARE THINKING ABOUT HOW TO
PREVENT IT FROM HAPPENING AGAIN.
THE THEME IS ALL TOO FAMILIAR IN
COLUMBINE, COLORADO.
RESIDENTS ARE REACHING OUT TO
THE PEOPLE IN NEWTOWN.
OUR COVERAGE OF THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT CONTINUES
IN A MOMENT.
Before cold & flu season,
help prevent
with Lysol Disinfectant Spray.
And use the Lysol
No Touch Hand Soap
for 10 times more protection
with each wash.
This season, a good
offense is the best defense.
Lysol.
Mission For Health.
>>> GUN CONTROL IS ONCE BEING
DEBATED AFTER THE TRAGIC SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
IT'S TAKING PLACE IN THE
NATION'S CAPITOL AND RIGHT HERE
AT HOME.
>> PLEASE LAY OUT A PLAN OF
ACTION OF HOW WE MAY ADDRESS
THIS SCOURGE OF GUN VIOLENCE IN
OUR COMMUNITIES.
>> THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN GAVE RISE TO
ANTI-GUN RALLY OUTSIDE THE WHITE
HOUSE.
THEY WANT TO FURTHER RESTRICT
FIREARMS TO TODAY'S TRAGEDY.
IN CALIFORNIA WE HAVE THE
STRONGEST GUN LAWS IN THE
COUNTRY AS RANKED BY THE BRAID
DID DID I CAMPAIGN.
>> CALIFORNIA HAS THE LOWEST
FATALITY RATES FROM FIREARMS IN
THE NATION.
>> THEY ARE CONSIDERING
REINTRODUCING A BILL THAT CLOSES
A LOOPHOLE IN THE BAN.
MORE ARE IN FAVOR OF
RESTRICTIONS, A GUN STORE OWNER
SAYS THE CURRENT LAWS ARE JUST
FINE.
>> ISOLATED INCIDENTS, IT'S
TRAGIC BUT WE CAN'T KNEE-JERK
AND THINK THAT IS GOING TO SOLVE
THE PROBLEM BECAUSE IT REALLY IS
NOT.
IF PEOPLE WANT TO DO SOMETHING
BAD THEY WILL FIGURE A WAY TO DO
IT.
>> OTHER PEOPLE FEEL THINGS NEED
THAT NO CHANGE.
>> WATCHING THE GUN VIOLENCE IN
OUR SOCIETY.
I CAN'T STAND BY AND WATCH THAT.
>> HE GREW UP WITH GUNS.
HE ATTENDED THIS VIGIL AT THE
PLAZA TO REMEMBER THE LIVES LOST
IN CONNECTICUT.
>> YOU REALLY LOOK INSIDE OF THE
MIRROR AND TAKE A LOOK, MAYBE
CHANGE A FEW THINGS HOW WE DEAL
WITH GUNS AND WAY WE ISSUE THEM
AND HOW WE ENCOURAGE VIOLENCE IN
SOCIETY.
>> THAT WAS AMA DAETZ REPORTING.
>>> APRIL TODD, 1999 THE NATION
WAS HORRIFIED AT TELEVISION AND
SAW HIGH SCHOOL STUDENTS RUNNING
FOR THEIR LIVES IN COLUMBINE.
TWO STUDENTS SHOT 12 SOUNDS AND
TEACHER BEFORE FATALLY SHOOTING
THEMSELVES.
>> HERE TO PROVIDE ALL THE
SUPPORT THEY NEED AND MESSAGE I
WOULD LIKE TO SEND TO THEM, THEY
ARE NOT IN THIS ALONE.
>> HE SAYS DENVER HAS DETAILED
DIAGRAMS FOR ALL OF ITS SCHOOLS
AND HAS TAKEN STEPS TO LIMIT
ACCESS POINTS FOR BETTER
SECURITY.
HE DOES NOT THINK GUN CONTROL OR
TOUGHER LAWS WILL PREVENT MASS
KILLINGS.
>> COMING UP AT 8:47 AND LOOK
WHAT WE NEED TO KNOW.
>> WE A LITTLE SUNSHINE IN SAN
JOSE EARLIER.
CLOUDS WILL BE OVERTAKING THE
BAY AREA.
TEMPERATURES IN THE 30s.
30s AND 40s THIS MORNING.
LIGHT RAIN, BREEZY WINDS ON THE
WAY.
I'LL LET KNOW HOW SUNDAY LOOKS
AND NEXT WEEK WHEN WE COME BACK.
>> Katie: BAY AREA STUDENTS
WRITE LETTERS TO SANTA BUT NOT
THE TYPICAL LETTERS YOU WOULD
THINK OF.
HOW THEY ARE WORKING TO HELP
MAKE S
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS BOB,
A REGULAR GUY
WITH AN IRREGULAR HEARTBEAT.
THE USUAL, BOB?
NOT TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
BOB HAS AFIB:
ATRIAL FIBRILLATION NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
A CONDITION THAT PUTS HIM
AT GREATER RISK FOR A STROKE.
[ GPS ] TURN LEFT.
I DON'T THINK SO.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR YEARS, BOB TOOK WARFARIN,
AND MADE A MONTHLY TRIP TO THE
CLINIC TO GET HIS BLOOD TESTED.
BUT NOT ANYMORE.
BOB'S DOCTOR RECOMMENDED
A DIFFERENT OPTION:
ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
XARELTO® IS THE FIRST AND ONLY
ONCE-A-DAY PRESCRIPTION
BLOOD THINNER
FOR PATIENTS WITH AFIB
NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
THAT DOESN'T REQUIRE
ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING.
LIKE WARFARIN,
XARELTO® IS PROVEN EFFECTIVE
TO REDUCE THE RISK
OF AN AFIB-RELATED STROKE.
THERE IS LIMITED DATA
ON HOW THESE DRUGS COMPARE
WHEN WARFARIN IS WELL MANAGED.
NO ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING
MEANS BOB CAN SPEND HIS
EXTRA TIME HOWEVER HE LIKES.
NEW ZEALAND!
XARELTO®
IS JUST ONE PILL A DAY,
TAKEN WITH THE EVENING MEAL.
AND WITH
NO DIETARY RESTRICTIONS,
BOB CAN EAT THE HEALTHY FOODS
HE LIKES.
DO NOT STOP TAKING
XARELTO® RIVAROXABAN
WITHOUT TALKING TO THE DOCTOR
WHO PRESCRIBES IT FOR YOU.
STOPPING MAY INCREASE YOUR RISK
OF HAVING A STROKE.
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU DEVELOP ANY SIGNS
OR SYMPTOMS OF BLEEDING,
LIKE UNUSUAL BRUISING
OR TINGLING.
YOU MAY HAVE A HIGHER RISK
OF BLEEDING
IF YOU TAKE XARELTO®
WITH ASPIRIN PRODUCTS,
NSAIDS OR BLOOD THINNERS.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE TAKING XARELTO®
IF YOU CURRENTLY HAVE
ABNORMAL BLEEDING.
XARELTO® CAN CAUSE BLEEDING,
WHICH CAN BE SERIOUS,
AND RARELY MAY LEAD TO DEATH.
YOU ARE LIKELY TO BRUISE
MORE EASILY ON XARELTO®,
AND IT MAY TAKE LONGER
FOR BLEEDING TO STOP.
TELL YOUR DOCTORS
YOU ARE TAKING XARELTO®
BEFORE ANY PLANNED MEDICAL
OR DENTAL PROCEDURES.
BEFORE STARTING XARELTO®,
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
SUCH AS KID ANY CONDITIONS,
SUCH AS KIDNEY, LIVER
OR BLEEDING PROBLEMS.
READY TO CHANGE YOUR ROUTINE?
ASK YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
FOR MORE INFORMATION
INCLUDING COST SUPPORT OPTIONS,
>>> LISA ARGEN IS HERE WITH A
LOOK AT THE FORECAST.
>> WE HAD 29 AT FAIRFIELD AND
30s BUT WARMING UP A LITTLE BIT.
CLOUD COVER ADVANCING AND THAT
IS TAKING AWAY OF THE BITE IN
THE AIR.
EAST BAY CAMERA, ALL THE CLOUD
COVER AND LIGHT RAIN WILL BE
DEVELOPING IN THE MORNING HOURS,
CLOSER TO THE GOLDEN GATE
BRIDGE.
VISIBILITY HAS IMPROVED
SIGNIFICANTLY AS WELL AS THE
LIVERMORE VALLEY AND SANTA ROSA.
WE HAD SOME FOG WITH THE COLD
TEMPERATURES EARLIER.
NOW JUST A LOT OF CLOUDS OUT
THERE.
LIVE DOPPLER 7-HD DOES SHOW THE
RAIN.
IT IS RUNNING PARALLEL TO THE
COAST RIGHT NOW.
OUR FRIENDS IN CLOVERDALE AND
PARTS OF THE NORTH BAY COULD BE
PICKING UP SPRINKLES.
YOU CAN SEE THE RETURNS RIGHT
HERE.
THE RAIN IS OFF THE COAST.
THIS SYSTEM IS A WEAK ONE.
IT WILL CONTINUE TO PROGRESS TO
THE SOUTH AND SLIDE IN
THROUGHOUT THE DAY TODAY.
THAT IS GOING TO BRING US A
CHILLY RAIN WITH SOUTHWEST WINDS
UP TO 20 MILES AN HOUR.
35 IN NAPA.
SANTA ROSA, 32.
39 ON THE COAST.
40, SAN JOSE.
COLD TO START OUT ABOUT DRY
CONDITIONS, BUT SPRINKLES
THROUGHOUT THE MORNING HOURS.
WE'LL SEE THE RAIN BEFORE 11:00
IN THE NORTH BAY.
THEN AFTERNOON LIGHT RAIN THE
REST OF THE BAY AREA.
LEFTOVER SHOWERS TOMORROW.
THIS IS COLD SYSTEM ORIGINATING
FROM THE GULF OF ALASKA BROUGHT
TEMPERATURES BELOW ZERO IN THE
SIERRA NEVADA THIS MORNING.
11:00, YOU CAN SEE THE RAIN, LOW
SNOW LEVELS FOR LAKE COUNTY.
AS IT PUSHES THROUGH THE BAY, BY
THE AFTERNOON, LOOK AT MOUNT
HAMILTON, 4:00, WE COULD SEE
SNOW THERE.
WITH WIDESPREAD LIGHT RAIN
AROUND THE BAY IT WILL BE A RAW
AFTERNOON.
OVERNIGHT, SHOWERS AND BY 10:00
TOMORROW MORNING, WE'VE GOT
CLOUDY CONDITIONS.
ANOTHER SYSTEM, A LITTLE WARMER
ONE IS ON THE WAY FOR YOUR
MONDAY MORNING.
THAT WILL BRING THE WET PAVEMENT
SLIPPERY CONDITIONS.
THIS IS GOING TO BRING IN A
LITTLE BIT MORE RAIN.
THESE SYSTEMS WON'T AMOUNT TOO
MUCH.
TUESDAY AND WEDNESDAY LOOK TO BE
THE DRIEST DAYS WITH SUNSHINE.
FIRST SYSTEM OVER THE WEEKEND,
TENTH TO MAYBE A THIRD IN THE
NORTH BAY MOUNTAINS BUT JUST
TRACE AMOUNTS IN THE SOUTH BAY.
52 IN SAN JOSE.
50 AND BREEZY HALF MOON BAY WITH
RAIN SHOWERS SPREADING SOUTH.
53 IN MONTEREY.
SEVEN-DAY FORECAST, WE'LL SEE
TEMPERATURES STAY COOL AND LOOKS
LIKE THE MID-WEEK DRY SPELL
GIVES WAY TO HEAVIER RAIN AT THE
END OF THE WEEK.
>> AS THE TRAGIC CONTINUES TO
UNFOLD IN CONNECTICUT, REMINDED
THE GOOD IN THE WORLD.
WE WANTED TO SHARE A DIFFERENT
STORY OF HOPE AND LOVE.
HUNDREDS OF STUDENTS IN FREMONT
WROTE LETTERS TO SANTA CLAUS
ASKING HIM TO GRANT A WISH TO
SICK KIDS.
LYANNE MELENDEZ HAS THEIR STORY.
>> HOW MANY LETTERS DID OUR
SECOND GRADERS PIER HERE....
>> THESE ARE FEW OF KIDS THAT
WROTE A WISH ON A PIECE OF
PAPER.
>> MY FAMILY AND MY FRIENDS.
>> MY MOM AND DAD HAVE A GREAT
TIME IN THEIR LIFE AND NOT HAVE
TO STRUGGLE WITH IT.
>> FOR THE CHILDREN TO STAY OUT
OF THE HOSPITAL AND FEEL BETTER
ABOUT THEMSELVES TO BE OUT.
>> THEY THEIR SECOND GRADE
TEACHER ORGANIZED THE PROJECT.
>> IT CAN BE PEOPLE CLOSE TO
THEM.
IT CAN BE CHILDREN FROM MAKE A
WISH.
SOME OF THE KIDS WROTE ABOUT
WHAT THEY WISH FOR OBAMA.
>> EACH LETTER, MACY'S DONATED
$2 TO MAKE A WISH FOUNDATION.
ORGANIZATION GRANTS WISHES FOR
KIDS WITH LIFE-THREATENING
MEDICAL CONDITIONS LIKE SHELBY.
SHE ARRIVED AT LIMO AND HAD A
SHOPPING SPREE TODAY BEFORE
FLYING OFF TO MEET JUSTIN BEIBER
STUDENTS AND PARENTS MANAGED TO
WRITE MORE THAN 41,000 LETTERS.
>> HIGH HANDS HURT BUT I KEEP ON
DOING IT.
>> THE MAKE A WISH FOUNDATION
WILL NOW RECEIVE MORE THAN
$80,000 WHICH WILL BE SPENT ON
GRANTING WISHES TO ABOUT 80 SICK
CHILDREN.
>> WE WANTED OUR KIDS TO LEARN
TO GO FORWARD AND THINK OF
OTHERS FIRST.
PLUS WE'RE GETTING THEM TO
WRITE.
>> HE TOLD YOU US HIS BABY
SISTER HAD BEEN SICK.
>> I HOPE SHE GETS BETTER.
>> THE POWER OF BELIEVING.
>> STAY WITH
>>> WE HAVE BREAKING NEWS IN
OAKLAND, POLICE ARE ON THE SCENE
OF A TRIPLE SHOOTING IN THE AREA
OF 85th AVENUE AND INTERNATIONAL
BOULEVARD.
NO WORD ON VICTIM'S CONDITION.
WE HAVE A CREW ON THE WAY AND
BRING YOU THE LATEST ONLINE AT
ABC7NEWS.COM.
BEFORE WE GO, WE WANTED TO SHOW
YOU A LIVE PICTURE A FLAG AT
HALF-STAFF ALONG THE
EMBARCADERO.
PRESIDENT OBAMA ORDERED IT TO
HONOR THE VICTIMS IN
♪ WE WERE SKIPPING STONES
AND LETTING GO ♪
♪ OVER THE RIVER
AND DOWN THE ROAD ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
AT NATURE VALLEY,
WE KNOW NATURE COMES TOGETHER
IN AMAZING WAYS.
THAT'S WHY WE BRING TOGETHER
NATURAL INGREDIENTS,
LIKE DARK CHOCOLATE
WITH TOASTED OATS,
OR SWEET GOLDEN HONEY.
PERFECT COMBINATIONS OF
NATURE'S DELICIOUS INGREDIENTS,
FROM NATURE VALLEY.
♪
♪ I WAS THINKING
THAT I HOPE THIS NEVER ENDS ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA BARS,
NATURE AT ITS MOST DELICIOUS.
>> JACK HANNA'S "WILD COUNTDOWN"
IS SPONSORED BY NATIONWIDE
INSURANCE.
>> HI, EVERYBODY. I'M JACK
HANNA, COMING TO YOU FROM MY
BASE CAMP HERE AT THE COLUMBUS
ZOO. AND WELCOME TO "WILD
COUNTDOWN." TO MEET THE WORLD'S
MOST REMARKABLE ANIMALS--
IT'S JUST LIKE WATCHING
A FAMILY, THE BIG FATHER SITTING
DOWN THERE.
SOMETIMES I HAVE TO GO TO
EXTREMES.
>> IT'S ABSOLUTELY, INCREDIBLY
GORGEOUS.