AND MICHAEL STRAHAN!
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: THANK YOU, THANK YOU.
HI EVERYBODY.
GOOD MORNING, GOOD MORNING.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: GOOD MORNING EVERYBODY!
TODAY IS MONDAY, DECEMBER 17,
2012.
KELLY: THAT'S RIGHT.
VERY ROUGH AND DIFFICULT WEEKEND
FOR ALL OF US ACROSS THE NATION.
AS PARENTS AND AS HUMAN BEINGS,
WE CANNOT REALLY IGN IGNORE THE
COVER OF EVERY NEWSPAPER HERE.
OF COURSE, THE HORRIBLE SCHOOL
SHOOTING THAT TOOK PLACE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA GOING TO
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT TO VISIT
THE FAMILIES OF THOSE YOUNG,
TINY 6 AND 7-YEAR-OLD VICTIMS.
AND THE HEROIC TEACHERS AND
PRINCIPAL THAT REALLY, I THINK
DID SO MUCH TO NOT JUST PROTECT
ALL OF THE STUDENTS IN THAT
SCHOOL, BUT ALSO TO -- WELL,
MAKE THE ULTIMATE SACRIFICE IN
SOME CASES.
AND SO, I THINK THAT WHEN YOU
SAY THAT A COUNTRY IS PRAYING
TOGETHER, WE REALLY, I THINK ALL
ARE PRAYING TOGETHER.
AND ACROSS THE BOARDS, YOU SEE
HERE THAT OBAMA, PRESIDENT OBAMA
IS SAYING THAT HE WILL -- THIS
IS FINALLY GOING TO START THAT
CONVERSATION ABOUT TOUGHER GUN
LAWS.
MICHAEL: IT WILL OPEN UP THE
DIALOGUE ABOUT TOUGHER GUN LAWS.
I THINK THIS IS JUST SOMETHING
THAT'S BEEN DEVASTATING TO
EVERYBODY.
COMING TO WORK THIS MORNING, I'M
THINKING YOU KNOW, IT STILL
DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE.
AND I DON'T THINK IT EVER WILL.
I DON'T THINK ANY OF US WILL
EVER UNDERSTAND IT.
BUT IT'S
STAY TOGETHER, AND HUG YOUR KIDS
AND ENJOY YOUR FAMILY AND JUST
TALK TO YOUR KIDS ABOUT IT.
I THINK THAT'S REALLY IMPORTANT
AS WELL.
KELLY: THAT'S THE THING.
AS A PARENT AND AS A PERSON
LIVING IN THIS WORLD, I SORT OF
-- I DON'T EXPECT MUCH, BUT
HERE'S WHAT I EXPECT. TO SEND
I EXPECT TO SEND MY KIDS TO
SCHOOL AND I EXPECT TO SEE THEM
AT THE END OF THE DAY.
MICHAEL: YES.
KELLY: LIKE, THAT'S WHAT I
EXPECT.
AND WHEN SOMETHING LIKE THIS
HAPPENS, IT JUST GRIPS YOU, IT
GRIPS YOU IN YOUR SOUL.
IT'S ALMOST A PARALYZING EFFECT
WHERE YOU THINK THIS IS A
NIGHTMARE THAT COLLECTIVELY,
COLLECTIVELY AS A SOCIETY THAT
WE CANNOT WAKE UP FROM AND WE
CANNOT IGNORE IT.
I THINK TALKING TO CROUR
CHILDREN IS A VERY IMPORTANT
THING.
AND I WAS WATCHING SOME OF THE
NEWS.
I TRIED NOT TO -- I TRIED NOT TO
OVERINDULGE IN THE NEWS.
MICHAEL: BUT IT WAS HARD NOT TO.
KELLY: IT'S HARD NOT TO.
MICHAEL: BECAUSE WE'RE TRYING TO
MAKE SENSE OF IT.
ONE OF YOUR NATURAL THINGS, IS
TO EXPLORE, TO TRY TO FIGURE IT
OUT.
AND, THERE WERE A LOT OF THINGS
IN THE NEWS THAT WERE TRUE, A
LOT OF THINGS THAT WEREN'T TRUE.
AND WE -- LET'S GO TO LAURIE
STOKES WHO'S IN NEWTOWN RIGHT
NOW.
KELLY: SHE'S BEEN THERE ALL
MORNING.
THERE'S LAURIE.
HEY LAURIE, HOW ARE YOU?
>> MORNING MICHAEL, MORNING
KELLY.
JUST LISTENING TO THE TWO OF YOU
TALK ABOUT TRYING TO STRUGGLE
WITH WHAT HAPPENED ON FRIDAY,
THE BLOODLETTING IN A FIRST
GRADE ELEMENTARY CLASSROOM, IN A
WHOLE SCHOOL IN SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
EVEN FOR AN ADULT, IT'S SO HARD
TO GRASP.
AND TO UNDERSTAND, AS YOU TALKED
ABOUT, YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO BE
ABLE TO PUT YOUR CHILD ON A BUS
TO SCHOOL, OR DROP THEM OFF IN
FRONT OF THE SCHOOL, TO WATCH
THEM WALK IN WITH THEIR
BACKPACK, HAVE THEM TURNAROUND
AND LOOK AT YOU AT SMILE AND
KNOW AT THE END OF THE DAY
THEY'RE GOING TO BE THERE WHEN
TO TELL UP AGAIN TO TELL YOU
ABOUT THEIR DAY.
AND AS YOU SAID, IN THIS
PARTICULAR CASE, ON THAT DAY,
WHEN ALL THOSE CHILDREN WERE
ESCORTED SO THE FIREHOUSE SO
CLOSE TO WHERE THEY HAD BEEN
TRAINED, IN CASE OF AN
EMERGENCY, EVERYBODY GOES TO THE
FIREHOUSE THERE HERE IN NEWTOWN,
WHERE THEIR PARENTS WERE THEN
TOLD, COME, YOU CAN COME
YOUR CHILD.
BUT FOR THOSE PARENTS WHO CAME
TO THE FIRE HOUSE ON FRIDAY, AND
STOOD THERE AND THEIR CHILDREN
DIDN'T COME, ONLY TO BE TOLD
THAT YOUR CHILD ISN'T GOING TO
COME HOME AGAIN.
WE'RE STANDING AT A PARK, IT'S
CALLED TREADWELL MEMORIAL PARK,
RIGHT BEHIND ME IS WHERE THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE HAVE
BEEN HAVING THEIR PRESS
CONFERENCES TO UPDATE US ON
THINGS.
YOU MENTIONED LAST NIGHT AT THE
VIGIL IN WHICH SO MANY CLERGY
CAME TO TRY TO GIVE SOLACE AND
TIME OF GRIEF FOR THIS
COMMUNITY, AND SO MANY OTHER
THING, IN CULMINATING WITH
PRESIDENT OBAMA COMING AT THE
END, AND SPEAKING, CLEARLY WE
UNDERSTAND HE WROTE, HE WAS THE
PRIMARY AUTHOR OF THE SPEECH
THAT HE WROTE.
WE COULD TELL ON FRIDAY HOW THIS
HAD CERTAINLY TOUCHED HIM.
SO PROBABLY WANTED TO MAKE SURE
THESE WERE DEFINITELY HIS WORDS
THAT WE HEARD LAST NIGHT.
HOW AT THE END WHEN HE READ THE
20 NAMES OF THOSE LITTLE
CHILDREN IN THAT FIRST GRADE WHO
BECAME VICTIMS, ON THAT
HORRIBLE, HORRIBLE DAY.
AND FOR THIS COMMUNITY, IT GAVE
GREAT SOLACE.
THEY'VE COME TOGETHER, THEY'RE
BROKEN, BUT THEY'RE DETERMINED
TO STAND UP.
WITH, I WAS
THINKING ABOUT HOW OVER THE
WEEKEND, HOW NONE OF IT SEEMED
TO REALLY RESONATE.
SORT OF WANDERED, YOU FIND
YOURSELF GOING BACK AND FORTH,
BECAUSE NONE OF IT SEEMED REAL.
BUT TODAY THE REALITY REALLY
STARTS TO SET IN AS THIS TOWN IS
GOING TO BURY TWO OF THOSE FIRST
GRADERS, 6 YEARS OLD, BOTH OF
THEM.
ONE, NOAH POSNER.
A LITTLE BOY WHO LIKED TO FIGURE
THINGS OUT MECHANICALLY.
HIS UNCLE SAID HE KNEW HE WOULD
GROW UP TO BE A GREAT FATHER AND
CONTRIBUTE TO THIS WORLD AND BE
A GOOD PERSON.
AND THERE'S JACK PINTO WHO'S
ALSO 6 YEARS OLD THAT WE HEARD
SO MUCH ABOUT, WHO LOVED,
MICHAEL, THE GIANTS.
AND WHO ALSO LOVED VICTOR CRUZ.
VICTOR PAID SPECIAL TRIBUTE TO
HIM, CALLING HIM HIS HERO.
I UNDERSTAND THERE IS A CHANCE
THAT THIS LITTLE BOY WILL BE
BURIED A JERSEY WITH THE NUMBER
OF VICTOR CRUZ.
AND OF COURSE, WE STILL DON'T
KNOW IF THAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN
OR NOT.
THE SAME TIME THE INVESTIGATION
CONTINUES INTO THIS GUNMAN, 20
YEARS OLD.
WHO, FIRST SLAUGHTERED HIS
MOTHER AND THEN CAME TO THIS
SCHOOL.
INVESTIGATIONS INTO THE ARSENAL
THAT HE HAD.
THE FULL AUTOMATIC WEAPONS THAT
HE BROUGHT TO THIS SCHOOL AND SO
COWARDLY GUNNED DOWN THESE
BEAUTIFUL, INNOCENT LITTLE
CHILDREN.
BACK TO YOU.
KELLY: THANK YOU LORI, THAT'S
GREAT REPORTING.
AND I KNOW THAT YOU'RE A MOTHER,
SO I CAN SEE AND FEEL IN YOUR
REPORTING THE DEVASTA FEELI
WE ARE ALL FEELING.
AND IT REALLY IS, YOU CAN'T HELP
BUT PUT YOURSELF IN THE POSITION
OF THOSE PARENTS THAT WERE JUST
STANDING AND WAITING AND WAITING
AND WAITING FOR NEWS THAT THEIR
LITTLE ONES WERE SAFE, ONLY TO
BE TOLD THAT THE WORST HAD
HAPPENED IN FACT.
SO, THANK YOU FOR THE REPORTING
LORI.
MICHAEL: THANK YOU.
>> I CAN'T IMAGINE, KELLY.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH GUYS.
MICHAEL: THANK YOU LORI.
AND I KNOW YOU HAVE SOMETHING
HERE ABOUT TALKING TO YOUR KIDS.
KELLY: YEAH, YEAH.
SO I'VE BEEN SORT OF LIKE
AGONIZING BECAUSE I HAVE KIDS IN
THESE AGES, THEY REALLY ARE VERY
AWARE.
THEY'RE NOT TOO LITTLE, THEY'RE
VERY AWARE OF WHAT'S GOING ON
AROUND THEM.
SO I WAS -- ALL OF THEIR SCHOOLS
PUT OUT SORT OF THESE WEBSITES
ON HOW TO TALK TO YOUR CHILDREN.
THIS ONE IS COURTESY OF
"HUFFINGTON POST" AND IT SAID
YOU SHOULD A
YOU SHOULD ASK YOUR CHILDREN IF
THEY'RE OF A CERTAIN AGE, I
THINK THAT RECOMMENDATION IS ANY
AGE ABOVE 7 IS LIKE A GOOD TIME
TO START THIS DIALOGUE.
ASK THEM WHAT THEY ALREADY KNOW.
LET THEM KNOW THAT THE CHILDREN
AND THE TEACHERS IN THAT SCHOOL
DID NOTHING WRONG.
MAKE SURE YOU KEEP THE SAME
HABITS.
LET THEM KNOW THAT THEY ARE SAFE
BOTH AT SCHOOL AND AT HOME.
THAT'S THE THING.
LIKE HOME IS SORT OF LIKE THIS
PEACEFUL PLACE --
MICHAEL: A SAFE HAVEN.
KELLY: IT'S A SAFE HAVEN.
AND SCHOOL IS THAT OTHER PLACE,
YOU HAVE TO KNOW THEY GET BACK
INTO THIS ROUTINE, GO BACK TO
SCHOOL, THEY ARE SAFE THERE.
LET THEM ASK AS MANY QUESTIONS
AS POSSIBLE AND DON'T BOMBARD
THEM WITH THE NEWS.
AT A CERTAIN POINT, THESE IMAGES
CAN BE TOO MUCH.
CERTAINLY FOR ME AND I'M SURE
FOR THE CHILDREN AS WELL.
AND AGAIN, IT CANNOT BE SAID
ENOUGH, AND WE TALK ABOUT IT
HERE ALL THE TIME.
THOSE TEACHERS THAT ARE, YOU
KNOW SUCH HEROES, AND REALLY DID
THEIR BEST TO SOOTHE, COMFORT,
AND HIDE THEIR STUDENTS REALLY
IS --
MICHAEL: AND IN AN UNTHINKABLE
SITUATION.
BUT OUR THOUGHTS, OUR PRAYERS
ARE WITH EVERYONE.
AROUND THE COUNTRY, NOT JUST
NEWTOWN.
I THINK IT'S AFFECTED EVERYBODY.
SO OUR HEARTS AND PRAYERS AND
THOUGHTS ARE WITH EVERYBODY.
AND YOU KNOW, OUR SHOW, IT'S A
DELICATE BALANCE BECAUSE OUR
SHOW IS ABOUT ENTERTAINMENT.
KELLY: I KNOW, THAT'S THE THING.
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT YOU, BUT WHEN
YOU WOKE UP THIS I
DIDN'T FEEL LIKE IT.
DOES THAT MAKE SENSE?
MICHAEL: YEAH.
KELLY: I JUST DIDN'T FEEL LIKE
IT.
I WAS LIKE OH GOD, I DON'T KNOW
THAT I CAN DO THIS TODAY.
BECAUSE WE'RE SUPPOSED TO BE AN
ENTERTAINMENT SHOW.
AND YOU KNOW, THANKFULLY TICKETS
HERE ARE FREE, SO I FEEL LIKE
NOBODY IS REALLY GOING TO BE
LIKE WOW.
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT I'M SAYING.
I JUST FEEL THAT IT'S A VERY
HARD THING TO MOVE FORWARD
TODAY.
BUT WE ARE GOING TO TRY, WE'RE
GOING TO TRY TO MOVE FORWARD AND
GET BACK INTO OUR ROUTINE AND
MAKE A LITTLE BIT OF
ENTERTAINMENT, IF WE CAN, TO
SORT OF -- IF NOTHING ELSE BE A
DISTRACTION.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL:
MICHAEL: I THINK IF I HAD TO DO
THIS BY MYSELF, IT WOULD BE TOO
DIFFICULT, AND SO WE'RE HERE
TOGETHER.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO TRY, WE'RE
ACTUALLY GOING TO DO IT.
THAT'S HOW I FEEL ABOUT IT.
KELLY: OK.
MICHAEL: SO I GUESS, WE'RE GOING
TO DO WHAT WE DO, WE'RE GOING TO
ENTERTAIN YOU GUYS, HOPEFULLY
DISTRACT.
BE A DIVERSION FROM EVERYTHING
THAT'S GOING ON OUT THERE.
KELLY: THAT'S CORRECT.
MICHAEL: HERE WE GO.
KELLY: HERE WE GO.
IN OTHER NEWS, HILLARY CLINTON
FAINTED OVER THE WEEKEND.
[LAUGHTER]
LITERALLY, I'M LIKE IS THERE ANY
GOOD STORY TO REPORT?
NO, SHE DID, SHE FAINTED OVER
THE WEEKEND.
SHE HIT HER HEAD AND SUFFERED A
CONCUSSION.
SHE'S BECOME DEHYDRATED FROM THE
STOMACH FLU.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU KNOW ABOUT
THIS FLU BUG BUT REALLY TAKEN
HOLD OF THE CITY AND I GUESS
EVERYWHERE ELSE IN THE COUNTRY.
BUT, IT REALLY IS THIS VERY
INTERESTING FLU BUG THAT I KNOW
A LOT OF KIDS AT MY KIDS SCHOOL
HAVE HAD, AND SOME GROWN-UPS
THAT I KNOW HAVE HAD THIS
STOMACH VIRUS, WHERE THEY BECOME
DEHYDRATED AND DISORIENTED AND A
LOT OF TIMES FAINTING AS A
RESULT OF IT.
SO BE ON THE LOOK OUT FOR THAT.
DO YOU HAVE ANYTHING GOOD TO
SAY?
MICHAEL: I WAS GOING TO SAY
DEHYDRATED AND DISORIENTED, I
THINK THAT'S HALF OUR STAFF BACK
THERE.
BUT THEY'RE NOT SICK!
KELLY: THAT'S JUST HOW WE WALK
MICH
AROUND HERE.
MICHAEL: I HAVE A QUESTION.
WHAT IS THIS?
WHAT IS THAT?
ANYBODY KNOW WHAT THAT IS?
IT'S ABOUT 24 PAGES, I THINK?
WHAT IS THAT?
KELLY: THAT'S THE WORLD'S
LONGEST WORD?
MICHAEL: THAT'S THE WORLD'S
LONGEST WORD.
KELLY: ARE YOU SERIOUS?
I WAS KIDDING!
[APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: THE WORLD'S LONGEST
WORD, IN ENGLISH, SO EVERYONE
BEAR WITH ME AS I READ THE 24
PAGES.
KELLY: OK.
CAN YOU PRONOUNCE IT?
MICHAEL: IT IS A PROTEIN FOUND
IN THE HUMAN BODY.
IT IS CALL TITIN.
KELLY: THAT'S SHORT, THAT'S THE
ABBRIEVIATION.
MICHAEL: I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE
THINKING, TTITIN.
KELLY: I BELIEVE IF YOU WANT TO
PRONOUNCE THE WORD IN FRENCH,
IT'S TITIN.
MICHAEL: IT HAS 189,119 LETTERS.
I MEAN, COME ON.
KELLY: I FEEL LIKE THEY'RE
MAKING THAT UP.
MICHAEL: THAT'S LIKE HITTING THE
BUTTON ON THE TYPEWRITER.
KELLY: I MEAN WHO'S GOING TO
QUESTION THEM REALLY.
OH, YOU MISSED, THAT'S A SILENT
P.
MICHAEL: IT TOOK A GUY 213
MINUTES TO VIDEOTAPE HIMSELF
SAYING IT.
KELLY: REALLY?
DO WE HAVE THAT VIDEOTAPE?
[LAUGHTER]
MICHAEL: 213 MINUTES ON A 60
MINUTE SHOW.
KELLY: THAT WOULD BE AN
INCREDIBLE VIDEOTAPE TO WATCH
HIM ATTEMPT TO SAY THAT WORD.
WHICH, DO WE KNOW WHAT TITIN
MEANS?
MICHAEL: IT'S A PROTEIN FOUND IN
THE BODY.
KELLY: OH, YOU SAID THAT RIGHT.
MICHAEL: THE GIANT PROTEIN KNOWN
AS TITIN.
KELLY: DO WE HAVE THAT PROTEIN
IN OUR BODIES?
GELMAN: I ASSUME SO.
MICHAEL: I HOPE SO.
I GUESS.
KELLY: YOU HAVE EXTRA.
MICHAEL: I GOT A LITTLE
SOMETHING, SOMETHING, YOU KNOW.
KELLY: HEY, "THE HOBBIT" SET AN
OPENING RECORD.
$84.8 MILLION.
MY BOYS WENT TO SEE THAT MOVIE
THIS WEEKEND AND THEY LOVED IT.
THEY THOUGHT IT WAS AWESOME.
AWESOME.
MICHAEL: REALLY?
MY FAVORITE IS THAT SMEAGOL
CHARACTER.
KELLY: GOLLUM.
MICHAEL: GOLLUM.
THAT'S ONE OF MY FAVORITES.
HE CREEPS ME OUT.
KELLY: WHEN I PULL MY HAIR BACK
AND GET OUT OF THE SHOWER, AND
HERE HE IS, THIS IS WHAT I LOOK
LIKE.
[LAUGHTER]
I'M NOT KIDDING, I'M NOT EVEN
KIDDING!
THE RESEMBLANCE BETWEEN GOLLUM
AND ME BEFORE MAKEUP AND OUT OF
THE SHOWER IS STRIKING AND
ALARMING.
AND I THINK I HAVE A LAWSUIT!
BECAUSE I DON'T THINK THEY'RE
PROPERLY CREDITING ME.
MICHAEL: IF YOU LOOK LIKE THAT
WITHOUT MAKEUP, WHAT THE WORLD
DO I LOOK LIKE?
KELLY: THAT IS EXACTLY WHAT I
LOOK LIKE.
MICHAEL: HERE'S SOME HAPPY NEWS.
KELLY CLARKSON IS ENGAGED.
KELLY: OH.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: YES.
SHE GOT ENGAGED TO HER MANAGER'S
SON BRENDON BLACKSTOCK.
KELLY: I LOVE THAT NAME!
BLACKSTOCK.
MICHAEL: YOU'LL LOVE THIS EVEN
MORE.
BRANDON'S FATHER HAS BEEN
MARRIED TO REMEMBERA MCINTYRE.
KELLY: WHAT?
I HAD NO IDEA THAT REBA MCINTYRE
WAS REBA MCENTIRE BLACKSTOCK.
MICHAEL: THAT FEELS LIKE IT
COULD FIT ME.
BLACKSTOCK.
MICHAEL BLACKSTOCK.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: I SAW THAT ARTICLE,
THEY'RE SAYING IT'S NOT GOING TO
BE SNOW IN NEW YORK CITY THIS
CHRIRESSING.
MICHAEL: WHO WANTED A WHITE
CHRISTMAS?
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: EVERYBODY DOES.
MICHAEL: WELL, I LOVE IT WHEN
SNOW FALLS AND YOU DON'T HAVE TO
GO ANYWHERE.
IT'S LIKE THE BEST, JUST TO SIT
THERE AND LOOK AND SEE
EVERYTHING IS SO PRETTY, YOU
HOPE IT MELTS BY THE TIME YOU DO
HAVE TO GO SOMEWHERE.
BUT THE CHANCES OF A WHITE
CHRISTMAS IN NEW YORK CITY IS
ONLY 25%.
IT'S NOT GOOD.
ACCORDING TO ACCUWEATHER.
THAT ACCORDING TO OUR VERY OWN
SAM CHAMPION.
HE NEVER GETS IT WRONG.
GELMAN: WELL --
MICHAEL: YOU CAN'T DO THAT,
GELMAN.
GELMAN: HE'S NOT A MIRACLE
WORKER.
KELLY: WE HAVE A HUGE SHOW
TODAY.
PAUL RUDD IS HERE FROM THE NEW
FILM "THIS IS 40."
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
I WOULDN'T KNOW WHAT 40'S LIKE,
BUT I'VE HEARD.
NO, I SAW THIS MOVIE AND I
BELIEVE THAT IT'S A DOCUMENTARY
ON MY LIFE.
MICHAEL: AND THE WAY IT STARTS
OUT HAS ME GOING WOW, THAT'S 40.
AND CHRISTOPH WALTZ IS HERE FROM
THE NEW FILM JANE -- FROM THE
NEW FILM "DJANGO UNCHAINED."
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
AND HE, HANDS DOWN, ONE OF MY
FAVORITE ACTORS, ONE OF THE MOST
TALENTED ACTORS IN HOLLYWOOD.
KELLY: WE BEGIN OUR COUNTDOWN TO
CHRISTMAS WITH AN LESSON ON
CHRISTMAS ETIQUETTE.
ON GIVING GIFTS, TIPPING THE
PEOPLE THAT WORK IN YOUR LIFE,
THE PROPER BEHAVIOR AT HOLIDAY
GET TOGETHERS.
HOW NOT TO DRINK TOO MUCH.
MICHAEL: AND YOU CAN FOLLOW
ALONG AT HOME, BY ANSWERING
QUESTIONS ON OUR WEBSITE.
SO GO TO LIVEKELLYANDMICHAEL.COM
TO CHECK IT OUT.
KELLY: SO WE'RE ALL GOING TO
TAKE THE QUIZ TOGETHER?
GELMAN: PLAY ALONG AT HOME.
KELLY: GREAT.
MICHAEL: BUT YOU HAVE TO READ
ALL THAT TO GET YOUR ETIQUETTE?
KELLY: YEAH.
MICHAEL: ABOUT ETIQUETTE?
I GUESS SO.
THIS IS THE 18TH EDITION.
17 BEFORE THIS ONE.
YES.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: OK, EVERYBODY, IT'S THE
MOMENT YOU'VE ALL BEEN WAITING
FOR, TIME FOR FALL INTO THE
HOLIDAYS TRAVEL TRIVIA!
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
♪
[LAUGHTER]
MICHAEL: I'M CONVINCED THAT YOU
ARE TRYING TO HIT US.  US.
TWO THINGS I'M CONVINCED.
YOU'RE TRYING TO HIT US AND THAT
THOSE ARE THE WORST SEATS WHEN
WE DO THE SNOWFALL.
KELLY: TERRIBLE.
GELMAN: I'D NEVER HIT YOU.
OUR TRIVIA DANCER IS RENE
SPARKMAN FROM PLANT CITY,
FLORIDA.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
HEY RENE.
IS SHE WEARING GOLD PANTS?
I CAN'T SEE YOUR LEGS --
MICHAEL: OH, WOW!
KELLY: THOSE ARE COOL.
MICHAEL: WORK IT!
LIKE IT!
KELLY: LOVE SHINY PANTS.
HEY, ON THE PHONE IS RICHELLE
FROM NORTH HUNTING,
PENNSYLVANIA.
CALLER: HEY GUYS.
MICHAEL, I JUST WANT TO SAY
YOU'RE DOING AN EXCELLENT JOB.
LOVE YOU.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: THANK YOU, THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
BUT WE HEAR THAT YOU ARE ALSO
GETTING MARRIED SOON?
CALLER: I AM, YEAH.
MY BOYFRIEND OF SEVEN YEARS
PROPOSED BACK IN JUNE ON OUR
BOAT.
KELLY: WAIT, YOU'VE BEEN
TOGETHER FOR SEVEN YEARS?
DID YOU ALMOST DIE OF SHOCK WHEN
HE PROPOSED?
CALLER: YEAH, YEAH, I DIDN'T
THINK IT WAS EVER GOING TO
HAPPEN.
KELLY: WOW.
SO WHERE ARE YOU GOING TO ON
YOUR HONEYMOON?
CALLER: WE WOULD LOVE TO GO TO
HAWAII.
KELLY: LET'S SPIN THE WHEEL AND
FIND OUT WHERE YOU'RE GOING TO
GO.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
♪
KELLY: THIS IS A GREAT PRIZE,
THE ST. JAMES CLUB, MORGAN'S BAY
IN ST. LUCIA.
SEVEN DAYS, SIX NIGHTS ALL
INEXCLUSIVE COURTESY OF OR
BOITHS VALUED AT $8,500.
YOU HAVE 20 SECONDS AND ONLY ONE
GUESS.
GOOD LUCK.
MICHAEL: ALL RIGHT, HERE WE GO.
ON FRIDAY'S SHOW WE TALKED WITH
EWAN MCGREGOR.
WHAT DID EWAN SAY HE BUILDS AS A
HOBBY?
CALLER: BIKES.
KELLY: THAT'S IT, YOU GOT IT!
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
ANNOUNCER: CONGRATULATIONS, YOU
AND A GUEST WILL
DA
DAYS, SIX NIGHTS AT THE ST.
JAMES'S CLUB MORGAN'S BAY.
SET ON COLORFUL HILLSIDE
GARDENS.
THIS ALL EXCLUSIVE BEACHFRONT
RESORT OFFERS NIGHTLY
ENTERTAINMENT, FOUR RESTAURANTS
AND A HOST OF LAND ACTIVITIES.
YOUR PRIZE IS VALUED AT
APPROXIMATELY $8,500.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: HEY, YOU KNOW WHAT?
FIRST OF ALL YOU WATCH THE SHOW
BECAUSE I DON'T THINK YOU CAN
GOOGLE THAT.
AND I'M SORRY I MESSED UP EWAN.
CALLER: I TAKE NOTES ON THE SHOW
EVERY DAY.
MICHAEL: SO GOOD.
I'M SORRY ABOUT EWAN.
I REMEMBER WE DID EWAN IN AND
EWAN.
SO NOW ALL I CAN THINK OF IS
THAT.
SO CONGRATULATIONS, GREAT JOB.
CALLER: THANK YOU.
KELLY: NOW YOU GET TO HELP MAKE
THE LUCKY DAY OF A MEMBER OF OUR
STUDIO AUDIENCE WHO WILL RECEIVE
A $500 GIFT CERTIFICATE FROM
OMAHA STEAKS.
SO PLEASE PICK A NUMBER BETWEEN
1-236.
CALLER: WE ARE GETTINGING
MARRIED ON SEPTEMBER 14, SO 14.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: THERE WE GO.
ALL RIGHT, CONGRATULATIONS
RICHELLE.
CONGRATULATIONS SIR, YOU'RE
GOING TO EAT WELL.
STAY RIGHT THERE.
NEXT, PAUL RUDD.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
ANNOUNCER: STILL AHEAD ON
"LIVE," WE BEGIN OUR COUNTDOWN
TO CHRISTMAS WITH A HOLIDAY
ETIQUETTE LIST.
FROM THE FILM "DJANGO
UNCHAINED," ACTOR CHRISTOPH
WALTZ.
AND COMING UP NEXT, PAUL RUDD.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: WELL, WHETHER ON STAGE OR
ON THE SILVER SCREEN, HE'S ONE
OF OUR FAVORITE ACTORS.
PLEASE WELCOME BACK TO THE SHOW,
PAUL RUDD!
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
>> HOW ARE YOU DOING?
KELLY: HOW ARE YOU?
THE DOUBLE, THE DOUBLE GUEST.
SO WAIT, I UNDERSTAND THAT YOU
TWO USED TO BE NEIGHBORS?
MICHAEL: YES.
>> YEAH.
WE MIGHT HAVE EVEN LIVED IN THE
SAME BUILDING I THINK.
MICHAEL: YEAH, WE LIVED IN THE
SAME BUILDING.
THE FIRST TIME I MET PAUL, I'M
AT THE CONVIENCENCE STORE
UNDERNEATH THE BUILDING.
I SEE HIM, HE TURNS AROUND AND
GOES OH!
>> I WAS SO EXCITED BECAUSE
A.F.C. FAN OF YOURS, YOU WERE
STANDING IN LINE, I THINK I WAS
BUYING THE NEWSPAPER.
AND, I WAS LITERALLY -- I WAS
LIKE A YOUNG GIRL SEEING ONE
DIRECTION.
[LAUGHTER]
KELLY: YEAH.
MICHAEL: AND I WAS A LITTLE
TRIPPED OUT, I WAS LIKE YEAH,
YEAH, MAN.
UH-HUH.
>> IT WAS IN THAT SPLIT SECOND
WHEN YOU REALLY CAN'T EVEN KEEP
YOUR COOL AND THEN YOU TRY TO,
AND THEN YOU OVERCOMPENSATE.
OH, OH HEY MAN, HOW'S IT GOING?
[LAUGHTER]
MICHAEL: BUT IT WAS GREAT, HE
PARTIED BUT SHUT IT DOWN BY
10:00.
KELLY: I'M STILL THINKING ABOUT
WHAT A FANCY BUILDING IT IS YOU
HAVE A CONVIENCENCE STORE IN
YOUR BUILDING.
IS THAT'S INCREDIBLE.
>> WELL, IT WAS KIND -- I DON'T
THINK IT HAD ANYTHING TO DO WITH
THE BUILDING, BUT IT WAS NICE
BECAUSE YOU COULD JUST GET AN
EGG SANDWICH DELIVERED LIKE
THAT.
KELLY: INCREDIBLE.
>> GO DOWN AND GET COFFEE.
IT REALLY, YOU KNOW,
CONVIENCENCE WAS THE ROOT WORD
THERE.
KELLY: I HAVE TO CONGRATULATE
YOU FOR GOING BACK TO BROADWAY.
MY IN-LAWS WENT AND SAW YOU IN
THIS PLAY "GRACE" AND SAY YOU
ARE SPECTACULAR AND PHENOMENAL.
>> OH, WELL THAT'S NICE.
KELLY: SO THERE YOU GO.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
SO THUMBS UP FROM THEM.
THAT'S FOUR THUMBS.
THAT'S FOUR THUMBS BETWEEN THE
TWO OF THEM.
MICHAEL: HOW ARE YOUR HOLIDAYS
GOING?
YOU'RE ON A BROADWAY SCHEDULE,
SO I DON'T KNOW IF YOU'VE HAD
TIME TO SHOP.
>> I HAVEN'T HAD TIME TO DO
ANYTHING.
EIGHT SHOWS A WEEK, IT'S WRONG.
[LAUGHTER]
IT SHOULDN'T HAPPEN.
KELLY: WILL YOU HAVE, DO YOU GET
CHRISTMAS DAY OFF?
>> I GET CHRISTMAS OFF, BUT THEN
THE 26TH, WE HAVE A COUPLE OF
SHOWS.
THEY CRAM IN A LOT OF THEM RIGHT
AFTER THE HOLIDAYS TOO.
SO I'LL HAVE THE DAY.
KELLY: BUT NO PRESSURE FOR YOU
TO GET PRESENTS OR ANYTHING?
>> I HOPE NOT, IF THERE IS,
PEOPLE ARE GOING TO BE
DISAPPOINTED.
IT'S NOT GOING TO HAPPEN.
I'M GOING HAVE "GRACE" POSTERS
AND PLAYBILLS.
KELLY: WE BOTH SAW "THIS IS 40."
I HAVEN'T LAUGHED THAT HARD IN A
LONG TIME.
I HAD TEARS COMING OUT OF MY
EYES BECAUSE I FEEL LIKE IT'S A
DOCUMENTARY OF MY LIFE RIGHT
NOW.
AM I YOUR TARGET DEMO?
>> WE'VE HEARD THAT FROM A FEW
PEOPLE.
YOU KNOW, THE IDEA ABOUT MAKING
THIS MOVIE IS HOPEFULLY IT WILL
BE FUNNY.
I THINK IT'S FUNNY.
I HAVE NO PERSPECTIVE.
KELLY: IT'S SO FUNNY BUT ALSO
HAS SO MUCH HEART.
>> ALSO TACKLING SOME REAL
ISSUES THAT I THINK PEOPLE WHO
ARE MARRIED AND HAVE KIDS AND
ARE DEALING WITH PARENTS, YOU
KNOW, ALL THESE THINGS THAT WE
GO THERE.
AND HOPEFULLY IT'S DONE IN A
FUNNY BUT REALISTIC WAY AND IN A
WAY YOU DON'T REALLY SEE MOVIES.
MICHAEL: IT'S A JUDD AN TOW FILM
SO LIKE FIVE YEARS AFTER
"KNOCKED UP," PAUL AND DEBBY ARE
PARENTS NOW, RELATIONSHIP
ISSUES.
AND WE HAVE A CLIP.
KELLY: BY THE WAY HIS DAUGHTERS
ARE INCREDIBLE ACTRESSES.
I MEAN THEY'RE REALLY TERRIFIC.
>> I'VE KNOWN THEM SINCE THEY
WERE LITTLE AND TO SEE THEM KIND
OF, NOW THEY'RE REALLY, REALLY
TALENTED.
MICHAEL: LIKE YOUR KIDS, YOU
WATCHED THEM GROW.
>> I'M IN THE PROCESS NOW OF
TRYING TO LEGALLY ADOPT THEM.
KELLY: GOOD, GOOD.
MICHAEL: WE HAVE A CLIP.
IN THIS CLIP, PETE AND BARRY IS
DISCUSSING PETE'S ATTRACTIVE
EMPLOYEE.
>> SO, SO THAT'S THE GIRL WHO
WORKS, THAT'S THE GIRL WHO WORKS
FOR YOU?
>> YEAH, THAT'S HER.
>> SEEMS NICE.
MY WIFE WOULD NEVER LET ME HAVE
A HOT EMPLOYEE LIKE THAT.
>> YEAH?
>> EVERY WOMAN WHO WORKS WITH US
LOOKS LIKE THEY'VE BEEN IN SOME
SORT OF HORRIBLE ACCIDENT.
[LAUGHTER]
>> NOW YOU'RE MY SLAVE.
>> ARE YOU COMFORTABLE WITH THAT
AROUND YOUR HUSBAND?
>> OH, PETE WOULDN'T KNOW WHAT
TO DO WITH THAT.
[LAUGHTER]
>> YOU THINK OUR WIVES ARE
LOOKING AT US RIGHT NOW?
>> OH, DEFINITELY.
>> THEY LOOK LIKE PEDOPHILES.
[LAUGHTER]
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: MEGAN FOX IS THE HOT
EMPLOYEE.
>> MEGAN FOX IS THE HOT
AND ROBERT SMIGELE, WHO'S ALSO
KNOWN AS TRIUMPH THE INSULT
COMIC DOG.
KELLY: HE IS SO GREAT.
>> KNOWN AS HIS NOT AS HOT
FRIEND.
KELLY: I USED TO WORK WITH MEGAN
FOX ON A SITCOM.
I HAVE TO TELL YOU, I FORGOT HOW
FUNNY SHE IS.
>> SHE'S HILARIOUS.
KELLY: UNBELIEVABLY FUNNY.
>> YEAH, YEAH.
KELLY: SO I UNDERSTAND THAT YOU
HAVE AN AMAZING KNOWLEDGE OF
MUSIC.
AND WE'RE GOING TO PUT THAT
KNOWLEDGE TO THE TEST WHEN WE
RETURN.
WORRY GOING TO PLAY A LITTLE
GAME WITH YOU.
>> OK.
KELLY: STICK AROUND, MORE WITH
PAUL RUDD.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
ANNOUNCER: STILL AHEAD ON
"LIVE," ACTOR CHRISTOPH WALTZ.
[ Female Announcer ]
MARTINELLI'S GOLD MEDAL
SPARKLING CIDER
IS THE PERFECT CHOICE
FOR HOLIDAY GATHERINGS.
MARTINELLI'S IS NON-ALCOHOLIC,
FESTIVE LIKE CHAMPAGNE,
AND TASTES GREAT!
MARTINELLI'S: SINCE 1868.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: WE'RE BACK WITH PAUL RUDD
STARRING IN BROADWAY IN "GRACE"
AND ALSO IN THE HYSTERICAL "THIS
IS 40."
BUT THAT'S NOT WHY HE'S HERE
NOW.
WE UNDERSTAND HE HAS INCREDIBLE
KNOWLEDGE IN MUSIC.
HE CAN NAME IT AS LONG AS YOU
HEAR THREE BARS OF THIS.
>> WHERE DO YOU HEAR ALL OF
THIS?
KELLY: WE READ IT, AND THEREFORE
IT MUST BE TRUE.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: SO WE'VE CREATED A GAME
CALLED STUMP THE RUDD.
KELLY: STUMP THE RUDD.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
>> YOU EVEN MADE A GRAPHIC AND
EVERYTHING.
KELLY: WE SPARED NO EXPENSE.
MICHAEL: SO WE'RE GOING TO GIVE
YOU THREE OR FOUR LINES OF EACH
SONG AND UP TO YOU TO TELL US
ARTIST, YEAR --
>> YEAR?
MICHAEL: ARTIST, YEAR, NAME OF
THE SONG.
KELLY: AND THEY'RE GOING TO LET
THE MORE TALENTED SING ERGO
IRST.
♪ AND I KNOW JUST WHERE TO
TOUCH YOU
AND I KNOW JUST WHAT TO PROVE
AND I KNOW WHEN TO PULL YOU
CLOSER ♪
>> YEAH, THAT'S AN AIR SUPPLY
SONG --
[APPLAUSE]
KELLY: SO FAR YOU'RE RIGHT.
>> THE YEAR?
1984?
[BUZZER]
[LAUGHTER]
KELLY: SORRY, YOU NOW HAVE TO
TAKE OFF ONE ARTICLE OF
CLOTHING.
[LAUGHTER]
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: ALL RIGHT, IT WAS 1983.
MICHAEL: OH THERE ARE WE GO!
IT WAS NOT 1983.
>> 1983.
WHAT MONTH OF 1983?
KELLY: IT WAS A TUESDAY, IT WAS
SEPTEMBER.
MICHAEL: IN NEW YORK, PEOPLE TRY
TO TALK AND TRY TO MAKE US RHYME
BUT WE JUST WALK BECAUSE WE HAVE
NO TIME IN THE CITY IT'S A PITY
BECAUSE WE JUST CAN'T HAD, DON'T
MEAN NOTHING THEY KNOW WHO'S
INSIDE.
>> YEAH, THAT'S EASY, THAT'S MEN
WITHOUT HATS, THE SAFETY DANCE.
KELLY: NO.
[LAUGHTER]
MICHAEL: WHAT IN THE WORLD IS IS
THAT?
KELLY: YOU'RE WRONG.
>> NOT EVEN CLOSE.
DION WARRICK, THAT'S WHAT
FRIENDS ARE FOR?
[LAUGHTER]
MICHAEL: YOU'RE GOING TO BE
NAKED FOR REAL.
KELLY: EVEN I KNOW WHAT THIS
SONG IS.
IT'S TRICKY BY RUN-DMC.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: OK --
>> SEE, I THINK YOU WERE REALLY
PUNCHING HOLES THAT I'M A
MUSICAL --
KELLY: ARE YOU BORED YET?
>> NO, I WANT TO KEEP GOING.
KELLY: THIS IS THE MOST EXCITING
THING THAT'S HAPPENED TO ME ALL
DAY.
>> ME TOO.
KELLY: ♪ WHAT YOU SAY ABOUT
YOUR COMPANY
IS WHAT YOU SAY ABOUT SOCIETY
CATCH THE MIST
♪
>> THAT'S RUSH, NEWLY ELECT INTO
THE ROCK AND ROLL HALL OF FAME.
AND THAT WOULD BE TOM SAWYER,
THAT CAME OUT IN 19-I KNOW I'M
RIGHT SO FAR.
[LAUGHTER]
KELLY: I'M DYING.
>> SEE, THIS IS ONE WHERE I
THINK IS IT LIKE LATE 70'S OR
EARLY 80'S?
I'M GOING TO GO 1979.
KELLY: IT WAS 1981.
>> I ALMOST HAD IT!
OH!
KELLY: GOSH!
II FEEL LIKE I HAVE TO SAY THAT
YOU LOST, YOU LOST.
>> BY THE WAY, YOU'VE TOTALLY
STUMPED ME.
[LAUGHTER]
MICHAEL: AND I HEARD ALL OF THAT
COMING OUT OF YOUR APARTMENT
WHEN I LIVED NEXT TO YOU, MAN.
[LAUGHTER]
>> I KNOW.
KELLY: LISTEN, IF YOU WANT TO
LAUGH, THIS FRIDAY NIGHT, GO SEE
"THIS IS 40" STARRING PAUL RUDD.
IT IS REALLY A GREAT FILM.
OH, WE HAVE A PRESENT FOR YOU
FOR PLAYING.
>> REALLY?
KELLY: OH MY GOSH, THIS IS SO
NICE, ARE WE REALLY GIVING HIM
THIS?
I FEEL LIKE HE LOST.
>> YEAH, YEAH.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: "THIS IS 40" OPENS
FRIDAY, MAKE SURE YOU CHECK IT
OUT.
PAUL RUDD EVERYBODY.
>> THANK YOU.
MICHAEL: NEXT UP, CHRISTOPH
WALTZ.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
[ Female Announcer ]
QUAKER YOGURT GRANOLA BARS.
THEY'RE WHOLE GRAIN GOOD...
AND YUMMY GOOD.
REAL FRUIT PIECES.
12 GRAMS OF WHOLE GRAINS
AND A CREAMY
YOGURT FLAVORED COATING.
QUAKER YOGURT GRANOLA BARS.
TREAT YOURSELF GOOD.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: HE WON AN ACADEMY AWARD
FOR HIS WORK IN QUENTIN
TARANTINO'S "INGLOURIOUS
BASTERDS," THEIR SECOND FILM
TOGETHER IS THE HIGHLY
ANTICIPATED "DJANGO UNCHAINED."
PLEASE WELCOME THE GREAT
CHRISTOPH WALTZ.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: CAN I TOUCH YOUR HEAD?
OH, THAT FEELS NICE.
MICHAEL: YOU LOOK A LITTLE
DIFFERENT.
WITH THE HAIR CUT.
>> WHAT HAIR CUT?
THIS IS NOT THE HAIR CUT, THIS
IS GROWING BACK.
KELLY: I LIKE THE AUDIENCE'S
REACTION TO YOU BECAUSE I THINK
THEY'RE STILL AFRAID OF YOU FROM
"INGLOURIOUS BASTERDS."
[LAUGHTER]
DID YOU NOTICE THAT?
>> IT'S ALL RIGHT.
KELLY: IT'S OK.
MICHAEL: WELL CONGRATULATIONS ON
YOUR GOLDEN GLOBE NOMINATION.
KELLY: YES, WONDERFUL.
>> THANK YOU.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: FOR "DJANGO UNCHAINED."
>> THANK YOU.
MICHAEL: WHEN YOU KNOW THOSE
NOMINATIONS ARE COMING OUT,
WHAT'S IT LIK
HEAR OR DO YOU JUST LET SOMEBODY
ELSE TELL YOU?
DO YOU NOT WORRY ABOUT IT?
>> IT SOUNDS LIKE I DO THAT
EVERY DAY.
THE WAY YOU PUT IT.
MICHAEL: WELL, YOU SHOULD THE
WAY YOUR PERFORMANCE IS
INCREDIBLE.
>> WELL, THANK YOU.
I WAS AT "THE TODAY" SHOW IN THE
STUDIO AND THEY PULLED ME IN
VERY EARLY AND I THOUGHT I WAS
FINE IN THE GREEN ROOM.
THEY PUT ME IN FRONT OF A
MONITOR.
I THOUGHT I WAS HERE TO BE ON
THE SHOW, NOT TO WATCH IT.
THEN, ON CAME THE ANNOUNCEMENT
OF THE NOMINATIONS.
SO, I WAS UNAWARE OF THE FACT
THAT THEY ANNOUNCE ALPHABETICAL
ORDER.
THESE NAMES COME UP, PHILLIP
SEYMOUR HOFFMAN, ALAN ARKIN AND
LEO DICAP RIO, AND TOMMY LEE
JONES.
I MADE HI PEACE WITH IT.
I'M VERY BUSY, I HAVE OTHER
STUFF TO DO ANYWAY.
KELLY: THERE YOU ARE.
>> AND IT WAS --
KELLY: EXCITING?
>> THERE'S ONE WORD THAT I WOULD
CALL IT.
SHOCK.
KELLY: SHOCK.
>> VERY POSITIVE, SHOCK.
BUT SHOCK.
MICHAEL: WHEN EVER YOU DO, SO
WHEN EVER YOU DO A ROLE LIKE
THIS, TO ME IT SEEMS LIKE YOU
REALLY ARE THAT CHARACTER.
KELLY: YEAH.
MICHAEL: WHEN YOU GET A
NOMINATION, WHY IS IT SHOCK?
>> NO, NO, YOU KNOW, SHOCKED
DOES NOT HAVE TO BE HORROR OR
TERROR.
IT CAN BE A VERY -- BUT IT'S
LIKE.
MICHAEL: HAPPINESS OUT OF THE
CHEST.
>> THE HEART BOUNCES.
KELLY: YEAH.
TELL US ABOUT, THIS IS YOUR
SECOND FILM WITH QUENTIN
TARANTINO SO HE MUST BE A
TREMENDOUS FAN OF YOUR WORK.
WHAT SIT LIKE WORKING WITH HIM?
>> I DON'T KNOW IF HE'S A FAN,
WE HAVE AN UNDERSTANDING THAT
IS, THAT CAN TAKE THE WORK OF
BOTH OF US, I MEAN, HIS WRITING
AND MY ACTING.
TO MAYBE A LEVEL THAT WE, IN
THAT ONE RESPECT WOULDN'T BE
ABLE TO INDIVIDUALLY.
I DON'T KNOW.
THAT'S WHAT I DELUDE MYSELF INTO
BELIEVING.
MICHAEL: WHEN W WRITING
"DJANGO" DID HE CALL YOU IN TO
WRITE THIS WITH YOU OR DID HE
SAY HE WROTE THIS FOR YOU?
>> HE HAD A WONDERFUL WAY OF
COMMUNICATING TO ME THAT HE
WROTE IT FOR ME.
HE PUT ME ON HIS KITCHEN TABLE
AND PUT THE PAGES IN FRONT OF ME
AS THEY CAME OUT OF THE PRINTER.
I WAS READING BIT BY BIT AND
EYEING IT OUT OF THE CORNER OF
MY EYE.
KELLY: LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT A
SCENE FROM "DJANGO UNCHAINED."
YOU'RE TALKING TO DJANGO BEING A
BOUNTY HUNTER LOOKING FOR PLAIN
TATION OWNERS.
IS THAT CORRECT?
>> ALMOST.
KELLY: ALMOST.
TAKE A LOOK.
>> YOU KILL PEOPLE AND THEY GIVE
YOU A REWARD?
>> CERTAIN PEOPLE, YEAH.
>> BAD PEOPLE?
>> AH!
BADDER THEY ARE, THE BIGGER THE
REWARD.
WHICH BRINGS ME TO YOU.
I MUST ADMIT I'M AT A BIT OF A
QUANDRY WHEN IT COMES TO YOU.
ON THE ONE HAND I DESPISE
SLAVERY, ON THE OTHER HAND, I
NEED YOUR HELP IF YOU'RE NOT IN
A POSITION TO REFUSE ALL THE
BETTER.
I'M LOOKING FOR THE BRITTLE
BROTHERS.
HOWEVER, I'M AT A SLIGHT
DISADVANTAGE.
SO FAR AS I DON'T KNOW WHAT THEY
LOOK LIKE.
BUT YOU DO.
DON'T YOU?
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: IT'S "DJANGO UNCHAINED,"
AN INCREDIBLE FILM.
IT OPENS CHRISTMAS DAY, GO AND
SEE "DJANGO UNCHAINED."
THE GREAT CHRISTOPH WALTZ.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
GOOD LUCK WITH THE GOLDEN
GLOBES.
>> THANK YOU.
MICHAEL: NEXT UP, A LESSON IN
HOLIDAY ETIQUETTE.
SO STAY RIGHT THERE.
ANNOUNCER: THURSDAY ON "LIVE,"
FROM "DJANGO UNCHAINED,"
ACTOR SAMUEL L. JACKSON.
NEXT "LIVE," SETH ROGEN AND A
PERFORMANCE FROM "ANNIE."
KELLY: ♪ THE SUN WILL COME OUT
TOMORROW ♪
MICHAEL: ACTUALLY IT SAYS IT
WILL BE OVERCAST WITH A CHANCE
OF RAIN.
ANNOUNCER: NEXT "LIVE" IS ONLY
--
MICHAEL: A DAY AWAY.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: WE'RE KICKING OFF OUR
COUNTDOWN TO CHRISTMAS WEEK
TODAY AND I KNOW MANY OF US HAVE
QUESTIONS ABOUT HOLIDAY
ETIQUETTE THIS TIME OF YEAR.
SO, HERE WITH SOME ANSWERS IS
LIZZY POST, THE AUTHOR OF "EMILY
POST'S ETIQUETTE" 18TH EDITION!
MICHAEL: NOW 18TH EDITION.
YOU ARE THE GREAT, GREAT
GRANDDAUGHTER OF EMILY POST.
YOU'VE BEEN TO A LOT OF FANCY
PARTIES, LOT OF PROPER ETIQUETTE
IN YOUR LIFE.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A QUICK
BREAK AND WHEN WE COME BACK --
KELLY: WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A
TEST.
MICHAEL: WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
ANNOUNCER: TOMORROW ON "LIVE,"
OUR COUNTDOWN TO CHRISTMAS
CONTINUES WITH A PERFORMANCE
FROM BROADWAY'S "ANNIE." "ANNIE"
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: WE'RE BACK WITH
ETIQUETTE EXPERT LIZZIE POST.
WE'RE LEARNING HOW WE CAN BE ON
OUR BEST BEHALVOR THIS HOLIDAY
SEASON BECAUSE WE NEED TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT ETIQUETTE.
LIZZIE WILL PUT US THROUGH THE
TEST BY ASKING US QUESTIONS.
YOU CAN PLAY ALONG AT HOME BY
GOING ON THE WEBSITE.
SO LIZZIE, WE'RE READY TO GO.
WHAT'S YOURS FIRST QUESTION?
>> FIRST STATEMENT IS, IF A
GUEST BRINGS EXTRA PEOPLE WITH
THEM, THEY MUST BE TURNED AWAY
AT THE DOOR.
OH!
[LAUGHTER]
MICHAEL: NO, FORGET --
>> SEND THEM BACK.
NO, YOU DEFINITELY WANT TO
WELCOME THEM IN --
MICHAEL: OH, NO, NO, YOU HAVE
NOT BEEN TO MY HOUSE, YOU'RE NOT
BRINGING EXTRA PEOPLE.
[LAUGHTER]
>> NUMBER TWO, YOU SHOULD BRING
A HOSTESS GIFT TO A HOLIDAY
PARTY.
YES!
OK, GOOD.
WE GOT THE RIGHT ANSWER.
NUMBER THREE, YOU MAY DISCIPLINE
SOMEONE ELSE'S CHILD IF THEY
MISBEHAVE AT YOUR HOME. OSH --
>> OH, NO!
MICHAEL: YOU DIDN'T GROW UP IN
MY HOUSE!
[LAUGHTER]
>> YOUR HOUSE, YOUR RULES BUT
YOU WANT TO LEAVE THE
DISCIPLINING TO THE PARENTS.
MICHAEL: CAN I DISCIPLINE THE
PARENT TO DISCIPLINE THEIR
CHILD?
>> I LIKE THAT, WE CAN ADD THAT
TO THE BOOK.
KELLY: ISN'T IT FINE,
SWEETHEART, WE DON'T WATCH
INTERNET PORN IN OUR HOUSE?
[LAUGHTER]
>> THAT IS A VERY, VERY
IMPORTANT ONE.
IT'S ON PAGE 452.
YOU SHOULD PUT YOUR PHONE AWAY
AND NOT TEXT OR USE IT AT THE
HOLIDAY TABLE.
I LOVE YOU GUYS, YES, VERY TRUE.
MICHAEL: HOW MANY OF US SLEEP
WITH THE THING.
KELLY: MARK CONSUELOS!
>> REGIFTING IS NEVER ACCEPTABLE
UNDER ANY CIRCUMSTANCES.
FALSE, ABSOLUTELY, THERE ARE
CERTAIN RULES FOR REGIFTING, WE
HAVE THEM ON THE WEBSITE AT
EMILYPOST.COM.
MICHAEL: PERFECT.
>> IT IS OK TO CUT DOWN ON YOUR
GIFT GIVING LIST THIS YEAR IF
YOU NEED TO.
YOU BOTH.EAH.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: BE HAPPY YOU'RE GETTING
ANYTHING, THAT'S THE WAY I FEEL
ABOUT IT.
>> GIVING CASH LOOKS THOUGHTLESS
AND COLD.
FALSE!
CASH IS A PERFECTLY ACCEPTABLE
GIFT.
LOTS OF PEOPLE LOVE IT.
IT'S OK TO INCLUDE A BRIEF,
MODEST FAMILY UPDATE IN YOUR
HOLIDAY CARD.
KELLY: OH MY GOSH.
I'M GOING TO SAY TRUE.
>> OK, KELLY YOU'VE GOT IT.
IT'S TRUE BUT YOU WANT TO KEEP
IT BRIEF, NO BRAGGING, NO SAD
NEWS.
MICHAEL: I DON'T WANT TO READ
ABOUT WHAT'S DOING ON IN
SOMEBODY ELSE'S HOUSE!
I HAVE ENOUGH TROUBLE IN MY OWN
HOME.
KELLY: YOU CAN FINISH THIS EXAM
ONLINE.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
REMEMBER, PICK UP THE 18TH
EDITION FOR MORE TIPS ON PROPER
ETIQUETTE.
WE WILL BE RIGHT BACK. ONTO
ANNOUNCER: LOG ONTO OUR WEBSITE
NEW YEAR'S EVE.
KELLY: AFTER THE SHOW WE'LL
FINISH OUR HOLIDAY ETIQUETTE
QUIZ ONLINE SO YOU CAN SEE US
THERE ONLINE.
TOMORROW'S
>> >> GOOD MORNING, STORM
WATCH ON THIS MONDAY YOU CAN
SIGH THE LIGHT RAIN SHOWING
NUPT EAST BAY SHORE LINE.
ALL THE WAY DOWN TO UNION CITY
AND FREEMONT.
LIGHTER RAIN AND MORE STUDIER
RAIN.
ALL THE WAY DOWN.
AND ACROSS 237 TO SUNNY VALLEY
AND SANTA CLAR.
THAT AREA RECEIVING MORE
STEADIIER RAIN.
WE ARE GETTING A FEW BREAKS IN
THE CLOUD COVER.
THAT IS A COLD FRONT THAL
BRING US AFTERNOON SHOWERS .
STAY WITH ABC NEWS FOR YOUR
MOST
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Announcer: IT'S MONDAY,
DECEMBER 17th.
COMING UP LIVE ON "THE VIEW" THE
WHOLE COUNTRY'S REELING FROM THE
SHOOTING RAMPAGE THAT LEFT 20
CHILDREN AND 7 ADULTS DEAD
INCLUDING THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER
AND ABC NEWS CHIEF LEGAL
CORRESPONDENT CHRIS CUOMO JUST
GOT BACK FROM THE CRIME SCENE IN
CONNECTICUT WITH THE VERY
LATEST.
>>> AND A FORENSIC PSYCHIATRIST
IS TAKING YOU INSIDE THE MIND OF
THE SHOOTER RESPONSIBLE FOR THIS
MASSACRE AND WHAT'S BEHIND THIS
TERRIFYING TREND OF GUNMEN ON A
RAMPAGE.
>>> THEN KADEE STRICKLAND HAS A
SNEAK PEEK AT HOW SHE'S TAKING
OVER "PRIVATE PRACTICE"