EARLIER WHO DESKRIEBLD AS A
MASKED GUNMAN.
WE CAN'T CONFIRM THAT UNTIL WE
HEAR FROM AUTHORITIES.
THE GOVERNOR WILL BE SPEAKING IN
ABOUT A HALF-HOUR.
PRESIDENT OBAMA BRIEFING WITH
HIS ADVISERS AND HE'LL BE
TALKING WITH THE NATION AT SOME
POINT THIS AFTERNOON.
HIS ROLE AS PRESIDENT BUT REALLY
HE'LL PLAY THE ROLE TODAY AS
FATHER IN CHIEF WITH HIS TWO
DAUGHTERS.
HE OFTEN SPEAKS ABOUT THEM ABOUT
HOW THEY INFLUENCE HIS ROLE AS
THE LEADER OF THIS NATION.
AND DAN, WE WANT TO COME BACK
N
NOW.
YOU DESCRIBED IN SUCH VIVID
DETAIL THOSE REDOUNIONREUNIONS.
YOU TALKED WITH SOME OF THESE
FAMILIES ABOUT THIS ORDEAL.
>> YEAH, JUST TO SET THE SCENE
AS I PREPARE TO SHOW YOU THIS
CONVERSATION, THIS BEHIND ME IS
THE VOLUNTEER FIRE HOUSE
LITERALLY RIGHT DOWN THE STREET
FROM THE SCHOOL, SANDY HOOK
WHERE THIS VIOLENCE PLAYED OUT
THIS MORNING.
THIS IS WHERE STUDENTS BROUGHT
BY THEIR TEACHERS.
PARENTS WERE TOLD TO COME PICK
THEIR CHILDREN UP AND THIS IS
WHERE THOSE REUNIONS TOOK PLACE.
I HAD A CONVERSATION WITH A
MOTHER AND HER CHILD IN THE
THIRD GRADE JUST A SHORT WHILE
AGO.
HERE IT IS.
>> WHAT HAPPENED?
>> THEY HEARD A POLICE COP CAME,
EVERYONE WAS SCARED AND I FELT
SICK AND I WAS GOING TO THROW
UP.
>> HOW DID YOU GET OUT?
>> WE HAD TO GO THROUGH THE
BUILDING AND GO TO FIRE HOUSE.
>> AND DID YOU KNOW WHAT WAS
HAPPENING AT THE TIME?
>> NO, UNTIL OUR NEXT-DOOR
NEIGHBOR MRS. WALKER, SHE SAID
THAT IF THERE'S A LOCKDOWN, JUST
BE CALM AND JUST, HER CLASS CAME
INTO OURS AND WE JUST LEFT.
>> WERE KIDS CRYING AND
SCREAMING?
>> YES, KIDS WERE CRYING, THEY
WERE ALL HUDDLING TOGETHER, THEY
FELT SO SICK.
>> HOW OLD ARE YOU?
>> 8.
>> 8 YEARS OLD.
>> ALEXIS.
>> YOU'RE IN FOURTH GRADE?
>> THIRD GRADE.
>> HOW DID YOU FIND OUT ABOUT
THIS?
>> THEY HAVE AN ALERT SYSTEM
THROUGH THE SCHOOL.
THEY SENT A MESSAGE SOMETHING
ABOUT LOCKDOWN.
AND SO, I FIGURED IT WAS THE
HIGH SCHOOL.
LITTLE DID I KNOW THAT IT WAS
THERE.
I CALLED MY HUSBAND CAN YOU FIND
OUT.
HE SAID GET IN THE CAR AND DRIVE
HE GOT HERE AND I GOT HERE.
HE HAD HER IN HIS ARMS AND YOU
KNOW, I'M CRYING.
AND SHE JUST GOES, MOMMA, I'M
OKAY.
I'M HERE.
IT DOESN'T EVEN SEEM REAL.
I'M SEEM REALLY, A SMALL TOWN,
YOU READ ABOUT THIS EVERYWHERE
ELSE BUT HERE.
IT'S HEART WRENCHING FOR THE
CHILDREN.
AND FOR THE PARENTS AND GRAND
PARENTS.
AND FOR EVERYBODY.
I JUST CAN'T FATHOM IT.
IT DOESN'T SEEM REAL.
SHOULD I BE PINCHED TO SEE IF IT
REALLY IS REAL.
IT'S HEART WRENCHING.
IT'S A NIGHTMARE.
IT FEELS LIKE A NIGHTMARE.
NEFF IN A MILLION YEARS WOULD
YOU EVER THINK, YOU DROP YOUR
CHILD AT THE SCHOOL, HUGS AND
KISSES, HAVE A GOOD DAY, I'LL
SEE YOU AT THE END OF THE DAY,
YOU NEVER KNOW.
20 MINUTES FROM NOW WHAT'S GOING
TO HAPPEN.
YOU COUNT YOUR BLESSINGS EVERY
DAY FOR WHAT YOU HAVE.
>> ALEXIS, I'M REALLY GLAD
YOU'RE OKAY.
YOU'RE PRETTY TOUGH.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
I'M SORRY.
A TOUGH, LITTLE GIRL.
DAVID, WHAT STRUCK ME THE MOST
ABOUT THIS INTERVIEW, THE BODY
LANGUAGE BETWEEN MOTHER AND
DAUGHTER, SHE WAS CLEARLY SO
RELIEVED THAT ALEXIS IS OKAY AND
ONE CANNOT FORGET THAT IN THIS
BUILDING BEHIND ME RIGHT NOW
THERE ARE PARENTS WHO DO NOT
HAVE THAT LUXURY OF KNOWING
WHETHER THEIR CHILD IS OKAY.
WE DON'T KNOW EXACTLY WHAT THEIR
STORY IS.
WE HAVE SEEN QUITE A FEW COUPLES
LEAVING HERE TODAY WHO ARE
DISTRAUGHT AND WITHOUT THEIR
CHILDREN AND ONE CAN ONLY
IMAGINE WHAT IT IS LIKE FOR THEM
THIS AFTERNOON.
>> WE HATE TO HEAR THAT, DAN.
THE MOTHER YOU WERE JUST TALKING
ABOUT, SO MUCH THE REFRAIN,
AFTER HORRIFIC SHOOTINGS LIKE
THIS ONE, HOW COULD IT HAPPEN
HERE?
IN THE LAST YEAR, THEY ENACTED A
GREATER SECURITY POLICY, YOU
CAN'T LOCK THESE SCHOOLS DOWN AS
WE ALL KNOW, THEY HAD TAKEN
PRECAUTIONS TO MAKE IT SAFER.
THE LITTLE GIRL WHO SAID I FELT
SICK TO MY STOMACH AND YOU CAN
ONLY IMAGINE WHAT HER
CLASSMATES, ALL OF THOSE LITTLE
STUDENTS WHO LINED UP TO GET OUT
OF THAT SCHOOL.
WHO WERE HIDING IN THAT FIRST
GRADE BATHROOM WITH THEIR
TEACHER.
ONE OF THEM SAYING I JUST WANT
CHRISTMA
CHRISTMAS.
I JUST WONDON'T WANT TO DIE.
I WANT CHRISTMAS.
YOU HEARD DAN ASK ALEXIS SPELL
HER NAME.
WE INTERVIEW THEM TO MAKE SURE
WE HAVE THEIR NAME AND AGE
RIGHT.
I WANT TO TURN TO JAKE TAPPER,
HE'S BEEN IN THE BRIEFING ROOM
AT THE WHITE HOUSE.
JAKE, WE'RE EXPECTED TO HEAR
FROM THE PRESIDENT A SHORT TIME
FROM NOW.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL BE
COMING TO THE BRADY PRESS
BRIEFING ROOM AT 3:150 WE'RE
EXPECTING SHORTLY BEFORE THE
GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT SPEAKS.
HE WAS BRIEFED ON THE EVENTS OF
THE DAY AT 10:30 THIS MORNING.
HE HAS BEEN BRIEFED THROUGHOUT
THE DAY.
HE HAD A CONVERSATION WITH THE
FBI DIRECTOR MUELLER AND THE
GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT AS WELL.
OFFERING HIS CONDOLENCES.
A DAY OF SOME ANGUISH WHEN THE
PRESS SECRETARY CAME OUT TO
BRIEF THE PRESS.
HE SEEMED SHAKEN.
BY THE NEWS.
WHEN ASKED ABOUT HOW THE
PRESIDENT WAS PERSONALLY
REACTING TO THE STORY, THE PRESS
SECRETARY WAS RELUCTANT TO
CONFIRM ANY OF THE DETAILS THAT
WE WERE STARTING TO GET.
AS A FATHER, EVENTS LIKE THESE
WEIGH HEAVILY ON THE PRESIDENT
AS A PARENT.
THE ROLE OF CONSOLER IN CHIEF.
COMFORTER IN CHIEF.
TRYING TO COMFORT THE NATION AT
SPECIFIC TIMES ABOUT WHAT'S
GOING ON.
AFTER THE TUCSON SHOOTING,
FILLED THAT ROLE.
OTHER PRESIDENTS GEORGE W. BUSH
WITH 9/11.
FULFILLING THAT ROLE.
IT'S A CHALLENGING TIME FOR ANY
PRESIDENT.
>> JAKE, YOU COVERED PRESIDENT
OBAMA WHEN HE WAS A CANDIDATE,
HIS FIRST TERM AS HE APPROACHES
HIS SECOND TERM.
YOU HAVE NOTICED BETTER THAN ANY
OF US, HOW OFTEN THE PRESIDENT
MENTIONS HE'S A FATHER, HE'LL
HAVE TO TALK ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
TODAY ONLY HE'LL HAVE TO DO IT
IN FRONT OF THE NATION.
HE OFTEN HAS TO LET THOSE
INSTINCTS AS A FATHER KICK IN AS
WELL, JAKE.
>> THAT'S EXACTLY RIGHT, DAVID.
WHEN IT COMES TO MOMENTS LIKE
THIS INVOLVING YOUNGER CHILDREN,
NO MATTER WHAT JOB WE HAVE, OUR
FIRST INSTINCT IS TO REACT AS A
PARENT, I THINK PRESIDENT OBAMA
HAS THAT AS THE REST OF US DO.
THE NEWS BEFORE US MANY OF US
DID IN THE PRESS.
IT DOES INFORM HOW HE SEEKS TO
CONSOLE THE NATION AND HOW HE
SPEAKS TO THE NATION THIS
EVENING THIS AFTERNOON
ESPECIALLY SPEAKING TO THE
PARENTS.
SO MANY MILLIONS OF PARENTS WHO
HAVE BEEN SHAKEN BY THIS E.
TODAY.
>> JAKE, THANKS SO MUCH.
YOU HAVE BEEN IN THE BREEFLG
ROOM.
IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE HOW QUICKLY
THIS UNFOLDED TODAY.
WHICH IS BELIEVED TO BE THE
WORST SHOOTING AT AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN THE UNITED STATES.
IT'S 10 AFTER 3 NOW.
WE HAVE WATCHED THIS UNFOLD.
WE APPRECIATE THAT YOU SHARED
THIS WITH US.
I WANT TO BRING THOSE WHO JUST
JOINED US UP TO DATE.
THESE ARE THE IMAGES FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
IT'S SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
IT'S BEEN FLASHED ACROSS SCREENS
ACROSS THE NATION.
IT'S BELIEVED THAT THEREABOUT
500 ATTEND THE SCHOOL.
THIS MOTHER DISTRAUGHT.
THERE WERE MANY, MANY REUNIONS.
WE KNOW THAT THIS AFTERNOON,
THERE ARE MANY PARENTS WHO HAVE
BEEN BRIEFED BY THE GOVERNOR
THERE IN CONNECTICUT.
MANY OF THEM LEAVING THE SCHOOL
DISTRAUGHT AND WITHOUT ANY
CHILDREN BY THEIR SIDE AS DAN
HARRIS REPORTED MOMENTS AGO.
THAT'S GOING TO BE THE MOST
DIFFICULT OF REPORTING THIS
STORY OUT.
IT'S TO WATCH AS THIS UNFOLDS IN
A TINY PICTURESQUE NEW ENGLAND
TOWN ON A SUNNY FRIDAY MORNING.
SCHOOL CHILDREN FINISHING THEIR
WEEK AND AS WE ALL KNOW, IF WE
HAVE CHILDREN IN OUR LIVES THAT
THE COUNTDOWN IS ON.
MANY MARKING HANNUKAH.
THEY WERE APPROACHING THE END OF
WHAT WOULD BE ANOTHER WEEK OF
TWO OF SCHOOL BEFORE THEY WERE
HEAD HOME FOR THE HOLIDAY.
WAIT FOR SANTA'S ARRIVAL.
AND MARK THE NEW YEAR WITH THEIR
PARENTS BEFORE HEADING BACK TO
SCHOOL.
THAT STORY FROM THAT FIRST GRADE
TEACHER AND THERE WILL BE MANY
MORE OF THESE STORIES.
I LOCKED MY SCHOOL CHILDREN IN
THE BATHROOM AND I TRIED TO
REMAIN POSITIVE.
ONE OF THEM SAID I JUST WANT
CHRISTMAS.
BOY, THOSE CHILDREN WHO WALKED
OUT OF THAT SCHOOL DESERVE
CHRISTMAS AND  TOLD, MANY OF TH
SCHOOLCHILDREN, TO LEAVE
EVERYTHING BEHIND, AS I
MENTIONED.
THOSE OF YOU WHO'VE BEEN WITH
US, I TALKED ABOUT THIS BEFORE
BUT THEY WERE TOLD WE NEED TO
LEAVE AND LEAVE ALL YOUR THINGS
BEHIND, THIS IS A COLD, CHILLY
MORNING HERE IN THE NORTHEASTERN
PART OF THIS COUNTRY.
MANY OF THEM HOLDING HANDS, AND
THE REACTION FROM THOSE TEACHERS
WHO LOOKED INTENT ON GETTING
THEIR CHILDREN OUT, CALM, BUT
YOU COULD SEE THE ANXIETY ON
THEIR FACES, AND WE'VE HEARD IT
AS THE DAY HAS UNFOLDED, HOW
COULD IT HAVE POSSIBLY HAPPENED
HERE.
WE DO KNOW THAT THE PRESIDENT IS
EXPECTED TO SPEAK SHORTLY.
WE WILL BRING THAT TO YOU FROM
THE WHITE HOUSE.
HE'S BEEN BRIEFED ALL MORNING
LONG.
HE'S REACHED OUT ALMOST
IMMEDIATELY TO CONNECTICUT'S
GOVERNOR DAN MALLOY WHO IS ON
THE SCENE.
HE OFFERED CONDOLENCES, SAID WE
WILL DO ANYTHING WE CAN FOR YOUR
STATE.
THE GOVERNOR THERE MEETING WITH
PARENTS WHO CAME FOR THEIR
CHILDREN AND DID NOT FIND THEIR
CHILDREN AT THE FIRE HOUSE.
AND HE'S EXPECTED TO SPEAK,
ALSO, WITHIN THE HOUR.
3:30 WAS THE TIME GIVEN TO US.
BUT AS WE KNOW, WE'RE HARDLY
KEEPING TO IT ON A DAY LIKE
TODAY WHEN THEY'RE DEALING WITH
RAW EMOTION THAT FOLLOWS SUCH AN
ENORMOUS TRAGEDY.
PIERRE THOMAS TRACKING THE
INVESTIGATION AND PIERRE, AS WE
WAIT FOR THE PRESIDENT TO
ADDRESS THIS NATION, WHAT'S THE
LATEST ABOUT THE GUNMAN, AND
ABOUT HIS RELATIONSHIP WITH
SOMEONE INSIDE THAT SCHOOL?
>> -- SHOOTER THAT HIS MOTHER
WAS AMONG THOSE KILLED AT THE
SCHOOL.
AND THAT SOME OF HER STUDENTS
MAY HAVE BEEN TARGETED.
>> PIERRE, WE BELIEVE THAT SHE
WAS, IN FACT, A TEACHER?
>> YES.
>> WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT THE
OTHER PART OF THIS
INVESTIGATION?
THAT IT MIGHT NOT JUST BE THE
SCHOOL THEY'RE LOOKING AT AT
THIS HOUR?
THAT THERE ARE AUTHORITIES
ELSEWHERE?
>> INDEED, DAVID, THE FBI AND
LOCAL AUTHORITIES ARE AT A
NUMBER OF SCENES INCLUDING THE
PARENTS' HOME.
THEY'RE DOING A METHODICAL
SEARCH.
WE'LL HAVE SOME ADDITIONAL
GUIDANCE ON WHETHER OTHER PEOPLE
HAVE BEEN INJURED.
WE'RE NOT QUITE READY TO REPORT
THAT INFORMATION JUST YET.
THAT IS ONE OF THE CONCERNS
GOING FORWARD.
>> SOME OF THE REPORTING COMING
IN FROM THE SCENE.
WE HAVE REPORTS AT THE SCENE,
SOMEONE WHO WENT TO SCHOOL WITH
RYAN LANZA, THE FATHER OF A
YOUNG WOMAN WHO WENT TO SCHOOL
WITH HIM, WENT TO HIGH SCHOOL
WITH HIM, HE'S 24 NOW SO THIS IS
A FEW YEARS BACK, SAID HIS
DAUGHTER HAD CALLED HIM TO SAY
SHE HAD HEARD WHAT HAPPENED AND
SHE DESCRIBED HIM AS A QUIET,
KIND OF KID.
SEEMED TO GET SORT OF LOST IN
THE SHUFFLE.
AND, OF COURSE, THAT'S JUST ONE
TINY PIECE OF THIS PUZZLE.
IT'S SORT OF THE FIRST LITTLE
WINDOW WE HAVE TO THIS
24-YEAR-OLD.
WE DO NOT KNOW WHAT THE MOTIVE
COULD HAVE BEEN THOUGH AS PIERRE
JUST REPORTED HE DID ENTER THAT
SCHOOL KNOWING THAT HIS MOTHER
WAS INSIDE.
HAD BEGUN HER SCHOOL DAY.
AS A TEACHER THERE AT THAT
CONNECTICUT ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE KNOW THAT AT LEAST 27 HAVE
BEEN SHOT AND KILLED, AND THIS
MORNING, JUST WATCHING THAT
NUMBER INCREASE, WAS FRIGHTENING
THING FOR MANY PEOPLE ACROSS
THIS COUNTRY AS THEY WERE TUNING
IN.
THAT'S WHERE IT STANDS.
AT LEAST 27, AND IT PUTS THIS
TOWN, NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, IN
THE HISTORY BOOKS FOR ALL THE
WRONG REASONS.
NOW THE DEADLIEST SHOOTING AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL OR A MIDDLE
SCHOOL IN AMERICA.
WE KNOW THAT VIRGINIA TECH STILL
RANKS AS THE DEADLIEST.
THAT WAS AN AWFUL SCENE.
WE ALL REMEMBER THAT.
COLUMBINE, OF COURSE, WE ALL
REMEMBER.
AND THIS COUNTRY JOINED ARMS AND
SAID WE WERE GOING TO DO
WHATEVER WE COULD TO STOP THESE
KIND OF SCENES FROM PLAYING OUT
EVER AGAIN.
ALTHOUGH IT IS ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE
TO DO.
THERE WILL BE TALK IN THE HOURS
AND THE DAYS THAT FOLLOW ABOUT
GUN LAWS IN THIS COUNTRY, ABOUT
MENTAL ILLNESS, ABOUT SIGNS THAT
COULD HAVE BEEN MISSED.
BUT THE TALK THIS AFTERNOON IS
ABOUT THE FAMILIES WHO'VE NOW
LOST LITTLE BOYS AND LITTLE
GIRLS AND MANY FAMILIES WHO ARE
WAITING FOR THEIR MOM OR DAD TO
COME HOME.
STAFF MEMBERS INSIDE THAT
SCHOOL, TEACHERS AND OTHER STAFF
MEMBERS WHO WE'VE BEEN TOLD
COULD NOT MAKE IT OUT, AS WELL.
WE'RE GOING TO HEAR FROM THE
PRESIDENT HERE MOMENTS FROM NOW,
AND AS JAKE POINTS OUT, SO
OFTEN, PRESIDENTS ARE CALLED
UPON AT THESE TIMES OF GREAT
NATIONAL GRIEF TO STAND BEFORE
THE CAMERA, TO BE -- THE
COMFORTER IN CHIEF.
HE'LL BE THE FATHER IN CHIEF,
BECAUSE HE OFTEN TALKS ABOUT HIS
OWN TWO GIRLS WITH GREAT PRIDE.
THEY HAVE DONE -- THEY'VE GONE
TO GREAT LENGTHS IN THE WHITE
HOUSE TO PROTECT HIS OWN
DAUGHTERS, AND HERE'S THE
PRESIDENT NOW, TO THE NATION.
>> THIS AFTERNOON I SPOKE WITH
GOVERNOR MALLOY AND FBI DIRECTOR
MUELLER.
I OFFERED GOVERNOR MALLOY MY
CONDOLENCES ON BEHALF OF THE
NATION.
AND MADE IT CLEAR HE WILL HAVE
EVERY SINGLE RESOURCE THAT HE
NEEDS TO INVESTIGATE THIS
HEINOUS CRIME, CARE FOR THE
VICTIMS, COUNSEL THEIR FAMILIES.
WE'VE ENDURED TOO MANY OF THESE
TRAGEDIES IN THE PAST FEW YEARS.
AND EACH TIME I LEARN THE NEWS,
I REACT NOT AS A PRESIDENT, BUT
AS ANYBODY ELSE WOULD, AS A
PARENT.
AND THAT WAS ESPECIALLY TRUE
TODAY.
I KNOW THERE'S NOT A PARENT IN
AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS.
KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS, MEN AND WOMEN WHO
DEVOTED THEIR LIVES TO HELPING
OUR CHILDREN FULFILL THEIR
DREAMS.
SO OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN TODAY.
FOR THE PARENTS, AND
GRANDPARENTS, SISTERS AND
BROTHERS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN, AND FOR THE FAMILIES
OF THE ADULTS WHO WERE LOST.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN FOR THE
PARENTS OF THE SURVIVORS, AS
WELL.
FOR, AS BLESSED AS THEY ARE TO
HAVE THEIR CHILDREN HOME
TONIGHT, THEY KNOW THAT THEIR
CHILDREN'S INNOCENCE HAS BEEN
TORN AWAY FROM THEM TOO EARLY,
AND THERE ARE NO WORDS THAT WILL
EASE THEIR PAIN.
AS A COUNTRY WE HAVE BEEN
THROUGH THIS TOO MANY TIMES.
WHETHER IT'S AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN NEWTON, OR A SHOPPING
MALL IN OREGON, OR A TEMPLE IN
WISCONSIN, OR A MOVIE THEATER IN
AURORA, OR A STREET CORNER IN
CHICAGO, THESE NEIGHBORHOODS ARE
OUR NEIGHBORHOODS, AND THESE
CHILDREN ARE OUR CHILDREN.
AND WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO COME
TOGETHER AND TAKE MEANINGFUL
ACTION TO PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS, REGARDLESS OF THE
POLITICS.
THIS EVENING MICHELLE AND I WILL
DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT IN
AMERICA WILL DO, WHICH IS HUG
OUR CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER,
AND WE'LL TELL THEM THAT WE LOVE
THEM, AND WILL REMIND EACH OTHER
HOW DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT, AND THEY NEED ALL OF US
RIGHT NOW, IN THE HARD DAYS TO
COME THAT COMMUNITY NEEDS US TO
BE AT OUR BEST AS AMERICANS, AND
I WILL DO EVERYTHING IN MY POWER
AS PRESIDENT TO HELP.
BECAUSE WHILE NOTHING CAN FILL
THE SPACE OF A LOST CHILD OR
LOVED ONE, ALL OF US CAN EXTEND
A HAND TO THOSE IN NEED, TO
REMIND THEM THAT WE ARE THERE
FOR THEM, THAT WE ARE PRAYING
FOR THEM, THAT THE LOVE THEY
FELT FOR THOSE THEY LOST ENDURES
NOT JUST IN THEIR MEMORIES, BUT
ALSO IN OURS.
MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF THE
VICTIMS, AND IN THE WORD'S OF
SCRIPTURE, HEAL THE BROKEN
HEARTED AND BIND UP THEIR
WOUNDS.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA ADDRESSING
THE NATION 3:20 IN THE
AFTERNOON, HOURS AFTER THAT
FIRST CALL CAME IN AFTER 9:30
THIS MORNING.
THE PRESIDENT THERE IN THE
BRIEFING ROOM WIPING AWAY WHAT
APPEARED TO BE TEARS, AND NOT
SURPRISINGLY, AS WE ALL WATCHED
AS IT'S AN EXTRAORDINARILY SAD
AND TRAGIC DAY WE'RE ALL
WITNESSING IN CONNECTICUT.
THE PRESIDENT SAYING I REACT NOT
AS A PRESIDENT, BUT AS A PARENT.
AND, JAKE, THIS IS -- THIS IS A
MAN WHO JUST ENDURED A TESTIFY
CAMPAIGN, HE'S IN THE MIDDLE OF
A FISCAL FIGHT IN WASHINGTON.
BUT WHEN WE OFTEN SEE HIM AT HIS
MOST EMOTIONAL MOMENT IS WHEN
HE'S TALKING AMONG HIS ROLE AS A
FATHER.
>> IT'S WHEN HE'S TALKING ABOUT
YOUNG PEOPLE, THAT'S EXACTLY
RIGHT.
AND, DAVID, I'M NOT SURE IF YOU
WERE ABLE TO SEE BUT LET ME JUST
TELL YOU FROM FOUR FEET AWAY
THOSE WERE ABSOLUTELY TEARS THAT
THE PRESIDENT WAS WIPING AWAY
FROM HIS FACE, SEVERAL TIMES
TALKING ABOUT WHAT IT MUST BE
LIKE FOR THOSE PARENTS TO BE IN
CONNECTICUT THIS EVENING,
TALKING ABOUT HOW THE MAJORITY
OF THOSE WHO WERE KILLED TODAY
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WERE
CHILDREN, AS HE DESCRIBED THEM,
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS.
BETWEEN 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
TALKING ABOUT HOW THEIR LIVES,
THE THINGS THAT THEY WOULD WANT
TO DO IN THEIR LIVES, HAVING
CHILDREN OF THEIR OWN, WOULD
NEVER HAPPEN.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN TODAY, HE
SAID.
AS A COUNTRY WE'VE BEEN THROUGH
THIS TOO MANY TIMES.
HE DID VOW THERE WAS ONE NOTE OF
POLITICS, SLIGHTLY, VAGUELY,
SAYING WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO
COME TOGETHER TO PREVENT FURTHER
ACCIDENTS LIKE THIS, FURTHER
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS FROM EVER
HAPPENING AGAIN, REGARDLESS OF
THE POLITICS.
BUT FOR THE MOST PART, HE STAYED
AWAY FROM THAT, TALKING ABOUT
THE NEED TO -- FOR EVERY PARENT
TO COME TOGETHER AND HUG THEIR
CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER THIS
EVENING.
AND OF COURSE, HE SAID, THERE
WOULD BE FAMILIES IN CONNECTICUT
THIS EVENING THAT WILL NOT BE
ABLE TO DO THAT.
IT WAS A VERY EMOTIONAL ADDRESS,
WITHOUT QUESTION THE MOST
EMOTIONAL I'VE EVER SEEN HIM
HERE AT THE WHITE HOUSE.
DAVID?
>> I'D HAVE TO SAY THE SAME
THING, JAKE, IN WATCHING HIM.
HE WIPED AWAY TEARS SEVERAL
TIMES.
I WAS MOVED, REALLY, BY THE SAME
THING, JAKE, WHEN HE POINTED OUT
THAT THE MAJORITY OF THE VICTIMS
IN THIS SCHOOL WERE CHILDREN,
AND HE SAID AS HE ADDRESSED THIS
PASSION, THEY WERE 5 TO 10 YEARS
OLD AND THEY JUST HAD DREAMS OF
MANY OF THEM WHAT SANTA WOULD
BRING FOR CHRISTMAS, WHAT THEY
WOULD CELEBRATE WITH THEIR
FAMILY DURING HANUKKAH AND THESE
RECENT DAYS.
MAKING IT THROUGH THE END OF
THESE NEXT COUPLE OF WEEKS SO WE
COULD HAVE THAT GREAT,
WELL-DESERVED CHRISTMAS AND NEW
YEAR'S VACATION.
AS JAKE POINTS OUT, HE SAID,
MICHELLE AND I WILL HUG OUR OWN
CHILDREN EVEN THOUGH MANY IN
THAT -- THAT REGION OF THE
COUNTRY, NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
WILL NOT BE ABLE TO DO THE SAME
WITH THEIRS.
ONE OTHER THING HE SAID, NOT A
PARENT IN AMERICA DOESN'T FEEL
THE SAME OVERWHELMING FEELING OF
GRIEF, AS HE WIPED ONE OF THOSE
TEARS AWAY, AND AS YOU LOOK AT
THESE PICTURES YOU CAN
UNDERSTAND, REALLY, HOW THE
PRESIDENT OR ANYONE WATCHING
TODAY, ANYONE WHO HAS CHILDREN
IN THEIR LIVES, TO IMAGINE THAT
THE CHILDREN OF THIS SCHOOL
WALKED OUT TO NOT ONLY HAVE THEY
ESCAPED THE SCHOOL UNDER THOSE
KINDS OF CIRCUMSTANCES, BUT THEY
WALKED OUT TO SEE, YOU KNOW,
TEARFUL ADULTS, AND CELL PHONES
WAITING TO HEAR WHETHER OR NOT
THEIR CHILDREN HAD SURVIVED.
AUTHORITIES WITH GUNS DRAWN.
WE KNOW THAT FOR QUITE SOME TIME
AFTER THOSE INITIAL CALLS THAT
THEY WERE OUT SEARCHING, NOT
ONLY THE NEIGHBORHOOD
SURROUNDING THE SCHOOL, BUT
GOING CAR-TO-CAR LOOKING INSIDE
THOSE SCHOOLS.
WE KNOW THAT THE TEACHERS HAVE
BEEN GIVEN ONE MISSION WHEN THAT
CALL CAME IN, WHEN THAT ALERT
WENT OUT.
THAT WAS TO GET THE CHILDREN OUT
AND TO THE FIRE HOUSE AROUND THE
CORNER.
YOU CAN SEE THIS PICTURE THERE.
ONE OF THE ADULTS TAKING
CHILDREN AWAY.
THE CHILDREN HOLDING HANDS, AND
ALL OF US, WATCHING WITH YOU AT
HOME, IN OUR STUDIO HERE IN NEW
YORK, WITH OUR MONITORS TAKING
IN THE SAME IMAGES YOU ARE, AND
MOVED BY SORT OF THE RESILIENCY
OF THESE LITTLE FACES.
MANY OF THEM LEAVING ALL THE
STUFF BEHIND, BEING WRAPPED ONE
OF THEM BY A FIREMAN IN A
BLANKET.
THE OTHER CHILDREN THAT WE'VE
SEEN WRAPPED IN THEIR PARENTS'
CLOTHES WHO SHOWED UP, THEY WERE
THE LUCKY PARENTS WHO SHOWED UP
AND FOUND THEIR CHILDREN WERE
WAITING AT THAT FIREHOUSE, HAD
TO GIVE THEM A HUG AND A COAT
AND NOW THE DIFFICULT TASK AS
WE'VE HEARD ALL MORNING LONG OF
TALKING IT THROUGH WITH YOUR
CHILDREN.
SENSING WHERE THEY ARE ON THIS.
AND THEN THAT TRICKY BALANCE
WHICH IS NOT TO OVERTALK IT, BUT
TO MAKE SURE THAT YOU'VE
ADDRESSED IT AND LET THEM KNOW
IT'S SO RARE, IT'S SO RARE, AND
REASSURE THEM THAT THINGS WILL
BE NORMAL AGAIN.
THE SHOCK OF AUTHORITIES WALKING
ACROSS THAT ROOF.
WE KNOW THEY SWOOPED IN VERY
QUICKLY, BEGAN WALKING THROUGH
THE SCHOOL, CLASSROOM TO
CLASSROOM, WE HEARD EARLIER
TODAY THAT DESCRIPTION.
THEY CHECKED EVERY CRACK, EVERY
CREVICE IN THE SCHOOL BEFORE
THEY DETERMINED THAT THEY HAD
SECURED THE FACILITY.
WE DO KNOW FROM PIERRE THOMAS'
REPORTING A SHORT TIME AGO THAT
NOT ONLY ARE THEY INVESTIGATING
THE HORROR INFLICTED AT THIS
SCENE THAT YOU'RE LOOKING AT
HERE, BUT THEY'RE ALSO AT THE
SCENE OF A HOME IN NEW JERSEY.
IT'S BELIEVED TO BE THE HOME OF
THE GUNMAN.
AND HIS MOTHER.
WHAT'S NOT KNOWN IS IF RYAN
LANZA STILL LIVES AT THAT HOME.
BUT WE KNOW HE'S 24 YEARS OLD.
OBVIOUSLY YOUNG AND WHAT WOULD
APPEAR TO BE A VERY TROUBLED
YOUNG MAN.
AND THE QUESTIONS IN THE DAYS
THAT WILL FOLLOW WILL BE ALL
ABOUT THE RED FLAGS, AND WHAT
COULD HAVE BEEN DONE AS WE
ALWAYS DO COME TOGETHER AS A
NATION TO TRY TO FIGURE OUT HOW
WE CAN TRY TO PREVENT THIS FROM
HAPPENING AGAIN.
ONE OF THE THINGS ABOUT THIS
STORY THAT MOVED US ALL IS THAT
THIS SCHOOL TRIED TO DO WHAT IT
COULD TO TRY TO BEEF UP SECURITY
EARLIER THIS YEAR.
ACTUALLY SENDING OUT A LETTER TO
PARENTS AT HOME SAYING THERE
WOULD BE NEW SECURITY PROCEDURES
IN PLACE.
IT WAS FOR THIS SCHOOL YEAR, IN
FACT, A SECURITY SYSTEM IN ALL
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS TO ENSURE
SAFETY, THEY WROTE.
AND THIS IS WHAT THEY WROTE.
EVERY VISITOR WILL BE REQUIRED
TO RING THE DOORBELL AT THE
FRONT ENTRANCE, PROBABLY SOUNDS
LIKE A SCHOOL IN YOUR PART OF
THE COUNTRY.
RING THE DOORBELL.
THE OFFICE STAFF WILL USE A
VISUAL MONITORING SYSTEM TO
ALLOW ENTRY.
VISITORS WILL STILL BE REQUIRED
TO REPORT DIRECTLY TO THE OFFICE
AND SIGN IN AND IF WE DON'T
RECOGNIZE YOU, YOU'LL BE
REQUIRED TO SHOW YOUR I.D.
PLEASE UNDERSTAND THAT WITH
NEARLY OVER 700 CHILDREN, OVER
1,000 PARENTS REPRESENTING 500
FAMILIES MOST PARENTS WILL BE
ASKED TO SHOW I.D.
YOU KNOW WHEN YOU'RE IN THE HEAT
OF A MOMENT TRYING TO PICK YOUR
KID UP AND RUNNING A BUNCH OF
ERRANDS I'M SURE THAT PROBABLY
CAN SEEM LIKE AN INCONVENIENCE.
BUT ON A DAY LIKE TODAY WE CAN
ALL UNDERSTAND THE IMPORTANCE OF
GOING ALONG WITH ANYTHING YOU
CAN TO TRY TO MAKE THAT SCHOOL
SAFER AND THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT IT
APPEARS THE SCHOOL TRIED TO DO.
DAN HARRIS IS AT THE SCHOOL.
AND DAN, I'M NOT SURE IF YOU'VE
HAD YOUR EAR PIECE IN.
I WAS JUST TALKING ABOUT HOW
SANDY HOOK ACTUALLY IMPLEMENTED
SOME ADDITIONAL SECURITY THIS
SCHOOL YEAR ALONE, NOT A SCHOOL
ON LOCKDOWN, BUT WITH HAVING TO
REPORT TO THE OFFICE AND SHOW AN
CRYDY.
AND IT WOULD SEEM THEY WERE
DOING JUST ABOUT EVERYTHING
POSSIBLE OTHER THAN, YOU KNOW,
BARRICADING THE SCHOOL, WHICH WE
ALL KNOW IS JUST NOT REALITY IN
AMERICA TODAY.
>> RIGHT.
I DID HEAR YOU.
HOW MUCH CAN YOU DO, ASIDE FROM
TURN SCHOOLS INTO FORT KNOX, HOW
MUCH CAN YOU DO TO BLOCK A
DERANGED PERSON WHO IS HEAVILY
ARMED AND INTENT ON KILLING
PEOPLE?
THIS SCHOOL CLEARLY TOOK EXTRA
MEASURES VERY RECENTLY.
TO IMPLEMENT SECURITY.
IT'S UNCLEAR, THOUGH, WHAT MORE
THEY COULD HAVE DONE TO PREVENT
WHAT TRANSPIRED HERE TODAY.
WE ARE STANDING IN FRONT OF THE
VOLUNTEER FIRE HOUSE WHERE
PARENTS HAVE BEEN REUNITING WITH
THEIR CHILDREN ALL DAY.
I SHOULD CLARIFY, THOUGH, THAT
WHEN WE CAME HERE SEVERAL HOURS
AGO WHAT WE WERE SEEING IS
PARENTS REUNITING WITH THEIR
CHILDREN, TAKING THEIR CHILDREN
HOME, WHICH IS QUITE POIGNANT.
WHAT WE'RE SEEING NOW IS
SOMETHING MUCH MORE DISTURBING.
WHICH IS WE'RE SEEING ONE BY
ONE, MANY FAMILIES LEAVING,
ESCORTED BY LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICERS, AND THESE ARE FAMILIES
WHO DO NOT HAVE CHILDREN WITH
THEM.
OBVIOUSLY WE DON'T KNOW THEIR
STORIES, BUT ONE CAN INFER THAT
AT LEAST SOME OF THESE PEOPLE
ARE PEOPLE WHO LOST THEIR
CHILDREN, PERHAPS TODAY, IN THE
LITTLE SCHOOLHOUSE DOWN THIS
STREET.
HARD TO MANAGE A MORE WRENCHING
CIRCUMSTANCE THAN TO HAVE TO
WALK OUT HERE IN FRONT OF ALL
THESE REPORTERS AND IN FRONT OF
ALL THESE LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICERS, SOME OF THEM WITH
TEARS IN THEIR EYES, SOME OF
THEM ON CELL PHONES, PERHAPS
UPDATING THEIR FAMILIES ON WHAT
TRANSPIRED HERE TODAY.
ALL OF THEM ESCORTED BY LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICERS TO THEIR
CARS, ON THEIR WAY HOME, TO A
HOME THAT WILL BE QUITE EMGTTY
FROM NOW ON FOR MORE THAN -- FOR
PERHAPS TWO DOZEN FAMILIES IN
THIS TOWN HERE TONIGHT.
>> DAN, REALLY MOVED BY THE
LITTLE GIRL THAT YOU
INTERVIEWED, HER NAME WAS ALEXIS
A SHORT TIME AGO IN OUR COVERAGE
HERE ON ABC NEWS, AND AS YOU AND
I BOTH KNOW, SOME OF THE MOST
HONEST PEOPLE OUT THERE WHEN WE
GO OUT TO DO THE STORIES EVERY
DAY IN AMERICA ARE THE CHILDREN
WE INTERVIEW.
AND WHEN SHE TOLD YOU, I JUST
FELT SICK, I FELT LIKE I WAS
GOING TO BE SICK.
AND I THOUGHT, WOW, THAT'S
PROBABLY HOW SO MANY OF THOSE
CHILDREN FELT, AND WHAT A BRAVE
LITTLE GIRL TO SHARE THAT WITH
YOU TODAY.
>> SHE WAS A BRAVE GIRL.
AND THAT REALLY WAS SUCH A
POWERFUL THING SHE SAID ABOUT
FEELING SICK.
SHE KNEW IN HER GUT THAT
SOMETHING VERY WRONG HAD
TRANSPIRED.
IN A CLASSROOM NOT FAR FROM
HERS.
SHE DESCRIBE D PEOPLE SCREAMING
AND CRYING.
SHE SAID THE SCREAMING WASN'T SO
BAD BUT THERE WAS A LOT OF
CRYING.
PEOPLE KNEW THAT SOMETHING WAS
DEEPLY AMISS.
IT WAS ALSO REALLY STRIKING TO
HEAR -- SORRY WE'RE IN A PLACE
WITH A LOT OF REPORTERS HERE, SO
THERE ARE PEOPLE WALKING BACK
AND FORTH IN FRONT OF THE
CAMERA.
IT WAS ALSO STRIKING TO HEAR
FROM ALEXIS' MOM AND TO SEE HOW
GRATEFUL SHE WAS TO BE WITH HER
CHILD.
SOMETHING ELSE HER MOTHER SAID
THAT REALLY STRUCK ME WAS SHE
FELT THE NEED TO PINCH HERSELF
AND NOT IN A GOOD WAY, JUST TO
REMIND HERSELF THAT THIS ISN'T A
DREAM, IT IS, IN FACT, A LIVING
NIGHTMARE.
THAT THIS HAS HAPPENED HERE IN
THIS SMALL TOWN OF FEWER THAN
30,000 PEOPLE.
AS WE DISCUSSED THROUGHOUT THIS
DAY, ONE NEVER EXPECTS SOMETHING
LIKE THIS TO HAPPEN ANYWHERE.
BUT THIS IS A TRULY UNLIKELY
BACKDROP FOR THIS KIND OF
HORROR.
THIS IS, AS I SAID, A TOWN OF
FEWER THAN 30,000 PEOPLE IN
SOUTHERN NEW ENGLAND.
A BEAUTIFUL PLACE.
KNOWN FOR HAVING A TOWN MEETING
HOUSE IN THE CENTER OF TOWN.
AN HISTORIC PLACE WHERE THE
CERTAIN MOMENTS IN THE
REVOLUTIONARY WAR, THE
UNDERGROUND RAILROAD PLAYED OUT
HERE.
THIS IS A TOWN WHERE THEIR TOWN
SYMBOL IS A ROOSTER.
THIS IS A QUINTESSENTIAL NEW
ENGLAND TOWN.
A TOWN, BY THE WAY, THAT I USED
TO COME VISIT WHEN I WAS A KID
BECAUSE I HAD FAMILY HERE.
A SMALL TOWN WITH LOTS OF
CUL-DE-SACS AND HAPPY FAMILIES.
TO HAVE THIS HAPPEN HERE IS
HORRIFIC.
>> DAN HARRIS, A NEW ENGLANDER
HIMSELF, REPORTING ON HOW
UNLIKELY THEY FELT THAT THEY
WOULD BE TARGETED BY SUCH HORROR
IN THIS LITTLE TOWN TODAY, UNDER
A CLEAR SKY, ON A CHILLY FRIDAY
MORNING, MAKING IT THROUGH
ANOTHER WEEK OF SCHOOL AND
TRYING TO GET CLOSER TO THAT
HOLIDAY.
AND DAN, WE THANK YOU FOR YOUR
REPORTING.
ONE OF THE MOST DIFFICULT THINGS
TO SHOW ONE OF THOSE SCENES, AND
STAND A RESPECTFUL DISTANCE AWAY
BUT TRY TO INFORM, REALLY, THAT
COMMUNITY AND THE NATION AS A
WHOLE OF WHAT'S TRANSPIRING.
I DID WANT TO LET OUR AUDIENCE
KNOW, IT'S NOW 3:30, OBVIOUSLY,
OUT HERE ON THE EAST COAST.
AND WE CONTINUE TO FOLLOW THE
SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AT AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
SANDY HOOK, ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
IT'S BELIEVED ANYWHERE BETWEEN
500, 700 KIDS GO TO SCHOOL THERE
EVERY DAY.
THE NUMBER ON YOUR SCREEN, AND
IT'S A NUMBER THAT WILL ETCH
THIS DAY IN HISTORY, AT LEAST 27
SHOT AND KILLED.
IT MAKES IT THE DEADLIEST DAY IN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN THIS
COUNTRY.
WE HAVE LEARNED FROM WASHINGTON
THAT THE FLAG, THE UNITED STATES
FLAG, WILL BE FLOWN AT
HALF-STAFF AT THE WHITE HOUSE,
AND UPON ALL PUBLIC BUILDINGS
AND GROUNDS, AT ALL MILITARY
POSTS AND NAVAL STATIONS, ON ALL
NAVAL VESSELS OF THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT THROUGHOUT THE U.S.
UNTIL SUNSET ON DECEMBER THE
1th.
YOU CAN SEE THE FLAG RIGHT
THERE, ABOVE THE WHITE HOUSE.
AND IT COMES JUST A SHORT TIME,
ABOUT 15 MINUTES AGO, THE
PRESIDENT STOOD BEFORE THIS
COUNTRY AND WIPED AWAY TEARS,
SEVERAL TIMES, AS HE TALKED
ABOUT ENDURING SO MANY OF THESE
TRAGEDIES, THAT HE REACTS NOT AS
A PRESIDENT, BUT AS A PARENT.
AND HE SURMISED THAT NOT A
PARENT IN THIS COUNTRY DOESN'T
FEEL THE SAME WAY HE'S FEELING
TODAY.
AND HE SAID THAT HE AND THE
FIRST LADY, MICHELLE OBAMA, WILL
EMBRACE THEIR LITTLE GIRLS, NOT
SO LITTLE ANYMORE.
THEY'RE GETTING TALLER AND
TALLER EVERY TIME WE SEE THEM.
BUT EMBRACING THEM WHEN THEY GET
HOME FROM SCHOOL.
HE WAS VISIBLY EMOTIONAL.
I THINK THE MOST EMOTIONAL I'VE
SEEN AND JAKE SAID THE SAME
THING, JAKE TAPPER AT THE WHITE
HOUSE.
AS HE PREPARES TO START HIS
SECOND TERM, AND THEY HAVE
WORKED SO HARD AS A FIRST FAMILY
TO SHIELD THEIR DAUGHTERS FROM
THE PUBLIC EYE, AND SO I CAN
ONLY IMAGINE SEEING THESE
LITTLE -- THESE LITTLE FACES
THAT ARE ON NATIONAL TELEVISION
TODAY, THROUGH NO FAULT OF THEIR
OWN, THROUGH NO CHOICE OF THEIR
OWN, THRUST INTO THE NATIONAL
SPOTLIGHT, BECAUSE OF THE
HORRIFIC SCENE THAT UNFOLDED AT
THEIR SCHOOL TODAY.
I DID WANT TO BRING IN PIERRE
THOMAS WHO'S BEEN FOLLOWING
DEVELOPMENTS AT THE WHITE HOUSE.
PIERRE, WE SAW THE FLAG FLYING
AT HALF-STAFF OVER THE WHITE
HOUSE.
WE HEARD THE PRESIDENT A SHORT
TIME AGO WE ALSO HEARD FROM HIM,
IT WASN'T OVERT POLITICS, BUT WE
DID HEAR FROM HIM THE NEED,
BECAUSE WE REPORT SO OFTEN ON
THESE CASES THAT NOW SOMEONE
WILL HAVE TO DO SOMETHING TO TRY
TO KEEP THIS FROM HAPPENING
AGAIN.
>> WELL, DAVE, IT'S FAIR TO SAY
THAT THESE TYPES OF SHOOTINGS
ARE BOMBING CHRONIC, PERSISTENT.
JUST THIS YEAR ALONE YOU HAD THE
SHOOTING AT THE COLORADO MOVIE
THEATER.
YOU HAD THE SHOOTING AT THE SIKH
TEMPLE.
REALLY SINCE VIRGINIA TECH IN
2007, WE'VE HAD MASS SHOOTINGS
LIKE THIS ON A PRETTY REGULAR
BASIS IN WHICH THREE OR MORE
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN KILLED.
AND WE'RE TALKING LITERALLY
HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE.
SO, I THINK THE PRESIDENT WAS
GETTING AT THE NOTION OF WHETHER
THERE'S GOING TO BE ADDITIONAL
GUN CONTROL MEASURES, THERE'S
BEEN A SPIKE IN GUN SALES IN THE
LAST MONTH OR SO.
IN FACT, THE DAY AFTER
THANKSGIVING THE FBI RECORDED
THE MOST BACKGROUND CHECKS EVER,
EVER, IN THE HISTORY OF THE
COUNTRY, IN TERMS OF HANDGUN
SALES.
AND RIFLE SALES.
AND MANY PEOPLE THINK THAT'S
BECAUSE PEOPLE WERE CONCERNED
THAT ADDITIONAL GUN CONTROL
MEASURES ARE COMING.
>> YEAH, AND SO MANY PEOPLE JUST
WANT TO FIND COMMON GROUND ON
THIS ISSUE IN THIS COUNTRY,
FEELING SO STRONGLY ABOUT THE
RIGHT TO BEAR ARMS.
BUT AT THE SAME TIME THE RIGHT
AS A PARENT TO PROTECT THESE
SCHOOLS.
>> DAVID --
>> YEAH, GO AHEAD, PIERRE.
>> ONE THING I WOULD ADD IS
LOOK, THIS IS A VERY COMPLICATED
PROBLEM.
THERE ARE SOME ESTIMATES THAT
THERE ARE OVER 300 MILLION, 300
MILLION GUNS ALREADY IN
CIRCULATION.
SO IF YOU STOP SELLING THEM
TOMORROW, THIS PROBLEM WOULD NOT
GO AWAY.
AS ONE SOURCE TOLD ME, GUNS ARE
NOT BIODEGRADABLE.
SO THIS PROBLEM WILL BE WITH US.
BUT AGAIN WITH THE SITUATION
DEVELOPING WHERE EVERY FEW
WEEKS, EVERY FEW MONTHS, HAVING
MASS SHOOTINGS WHERE PEOPLE ARE
IN WHAT THEY CALL SOFT TARGETS,
WHERE THE SHOOTERS GO TO PLACES
WHERE THERE'S LIKELY TO BE
LITTLE SECURITY, LIKELY TO BE
LOTS OF PEOPLE IN A CONCENTRATED
FASHION, AND MOW THEM DOWN, THIS
IS A QUESTION THAT THE COUNTRY
SEEMS IS GOING TO HAVE TO
ADDRESS AT SOME POINT.
>> NOT ONLY QUESTION WE'LL HAVE
TO ADDRESS BUT A CONVERSATION,
PIERRE, AS YOU POINT OUT THAT'S
ALREADY STARTED.
WE JUST GOT THIS FROM MARK
KELLY, OF COURSE, THE ASTRONAUT,
THE COMMANDER, THE HUSBAND OF
GABRIELLE GIFFORDS, THE
CONGRESSWOMAN WHO WAS SHOT IN
TUCSON, AND HE WRITES ON
FACEBOOK THAT THIS TIME OUR
RESPONSE MUST CONSIST OF MORE
THAN REGRET, MORE THAN SORROW,
MORE THAN CONDOLENCES.
THE CHILDREN OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND ALL THE
VICTIMS OF GUN VIOLENCE DESERVE
LEADERS WHO HAVE THE COURAGE TO
PARTICIPATE IN THE MEANINGFUL
DISCUSSION ABOUT OUR GUN LAWS.
SO THERE WILL BE SOME PRESSURE
TO ADDRESS THIS WITHOUT
INFRINGING UPON THE RIGHTS OF
OTHER AMERICANS WHO, OF COURSE,
FEEL SO STRONGLY ABOUT
PROTECTING THOSE RIGHTS.
SO IT'S A VERY CAREFUL, CAREFUL
DEBATE THAT WILL ENSUE IN THE
DAYS AND WEEKS TO COME.
BUT WE WANT TO GO TO GOVERNOR
DAN MALLOY IN CONNECTICUT THERE.
ADDRESSING THE NATION NOW.
>> LIEUTENANT GOVERNOR AND I
HAVE BEEN SPOKEN TO, AND IN AN
ATTEMPT THAT WE MIGHT BE
PREPARED FOR SOMETHING LIKE THIS
PLAYING ITSELF OUT IN OUR STATE.
YOU CAN NEVER BE PREPARED FOR
THIS KIND OF INCIDENT.
WHAT HAS HAPPENED.
WHAT HAS TRANSPIRED AT THAT
SCHOOL BUILDING WILL LEAVE A
MARK ON THIS COMMUNITY AND EVERY
FAMILY IMPACTED.
I ONLY ASK THAT ALL OF OUR
FELLOW CITIZENS HERE IN THE
UNITED STATES AND AROUND THE
WORLD WHO HAVE ALREADY OFFERED
THEIR ASSISTANCE, REMEMBER ALL
OF THE VICTIMS IN THEIR PRAYERS.
TO ALL OF YOU IN THE MEDIA, WE
WILL DO OUR BEST TO KEEP YOU AS
INFORMED AS WE CAN.
AFTER I'M DONE SPEAKING, A
REPRESENTATIVE OF THE STATE
POLICE WILL SPEAK TO YOU, AND
GIVE YOU SOME ADDITIONAL
INFORMATION.
EARLIER TODAY A NUMBER OF OUR
CITIZENS, BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN,
HAD THEIR LIVES TAKEN AWAY FROM
THEM.
AS WELL AS ADULTS WHOSE
RESPONSIBILITY IT WAS TO EDUCATE
AND SUPERVISE THOSE CHILDREN.
THE PERPETRATOR OF THE CRIME IS
DEAD, AS IS AN INDIVIDUAL WHO
THE PERPETRATOR LIVED WITH.
WITH THAT I'M GOING TO TURN IT
OVER TO PAUL VANCE WHO WILL
ANSWER OR WILL GIVE YOU SOME
ADDITIONAL INFORMATION, AND THEN
LATER IN THE DAY, PERHAPS WE'LL
SPEAK AGAIN.
AGAIN I THINK ON BEHALF OF THE
PEOPLE OF THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT, WE EXTEND OUR
CONDOLENCES, AS I HAVE AT THE
FIREHOUSE TO THE PARENTS OF
THESE -- THESE CHILDREN, AS WELL
AS THE ADULTS THAT ARE THERE.
I WANT TO THANK THE PRESIDENT,
WHO HAS BEEN ON THE PHONE WITH
US TODAY FOR HIS STATEMENT
RELEASED TO YOU A LITTLE WHILE
AGO, AS WELL AS THE STATEMENTS
HE MADE TO ME EARLIER -- MUCH
EARLIER TODAY, AS THE HOURS
RACED BY.
AND WITH THAT, I SHOULD ALSO SAY
THAT THERE ARE A NUMBER OF
PUBLIC OFFICIALS, INCLUDING THE
FIRST SELECTWOMAN WHO HAS BEEN
ON SITE THROUGHOUT THE DAY.
WE HAVE STATE REPRESENTATIVES,
STATE SENATOR, OTHER SELECT
PEOPLE WHO ARE HERE.
WE HAVE THE SUPERINTENDENT OF
SCHOOLS, WHO HAS DONE WONDERFUL
WORK IN HELPING US GET THE
INFORMATION NECESSARY TO BEGIN
THE PROCESSES THAT WILL BE
ONGOING FOR A NUMBER OF HOURS IN
ADVANCE.
I JUST WANT TO THANK SENATOR
BLUMENTHAL AND SENATOR-ELECT
MURPHY FOR ALSO JOINING US.
WITH THAT I'M GOING TO ABSENT
MYSELF, MR. VANCE WILL COME
FORWARD AND SPEAK TO YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> HI, GOOD EVENING.
I JUST WOULD LIKE TO RESTATE
SOME OF THE INFORMATION THAT WE
MADE AVAILABLE EARLIER.
WE'LL TAKE SOME QUESTIONS, BUT I
MUST PREFACE MY REMARKS BY
SAYING THIS IS AN ACTIVE,
ONGOING INVESTIGATION.
THERE IS A GREAT DEAL OF WORK TO
GO.
AND THERE IS A LOT OF THINGS
THAT WE CANNOT CONFIRM OR
DISCUSS AS OF YET.
BUT SHORTLY AFTER 9:30 THIS
MORNING THE NEWTOWN POLICE
DEPARTMENT RECEIVED A CALL FOR
HELP AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
UPON REALIZING THE INTENSITY AND
DIFFICULTY OF THE SITUATION, WE
WERE ON CALL FOR SURROUNDING
POLICE DEPARTMENTS AND STATE
POLICE TO ASSIST.
UPON ARRIVAL OF LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICERS AT THE SCHOOL THEY
IMMEDIATELY ENTERED THE SCHOOL
AS WE KNEW THIS WAS AN ACTIVE,
POTENTIAL ACTIVE SHOOTER
SITUATION.
THEIR FOCUS WAS TO SEARCH FOR
STUDENTS, FACULTY, AND STAFF,
AND REMOVE THEM TO A SAFE AREA
OUTSIDE OF THE SCHOOL.
THEY DID SEARCH EVERY NOOK AND
CRANNY, EVERY ROOM, AND EVERY
PORTION OF THAT SCHOOL AND
ACCOMPLISHED THAT TASK.
THEY TOOK THE RESCUED TO A
STAGING AREA TO REUNITE THEM
WITH FAMILY MEMBERS.
AS HAS BEEN REPORTED, THERE WERE
FATALITIES.
THERE WERE 18 CHILDREN THAT WERE
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCHOOL.
THERE WERE TWO THAT WERE
TRANSPORTED TO AREA HOSPITALS
AND PRONOUNCED DEAD AT AREA
HOSPITALS.
AND THERE WERE SIX ADULTS
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCENE AT
THE SCHOOL.
AS THE GOVERNOR REPORTED THE
SHOOTER IS DECEASED.
IS DECEASED IN THE SCHOOL.
THERE'S A GREAT DEAL OF WORK
GOING ON RELATIVE TO THAT,
THAT'S THE REASON WE HAVE NOT
IDENTIFIED HIM AS OF YET.
BY THAT I MEAN SEARCH WARRANTS,
EXAMINATION OF AREAS OF
RESIDENCE, EMPLOYMENT, AND ANY
ANCILLARY THINGS THAT MAY BE
ATTACHED TO THE IDENTITY AND TO
THAT INDIVIDUAL.
THE SCENE HAS BEEN SECURED.
NEWTOWN POLICE OFFICERS, STATE
POLICE MAJOR CRIME UNITS FROM
BOTH WESTERN DISTRICT AND
CENTRAL DISTRICT HAVE RESPONDED,
AND ARE WORKING WITH SEVERAL
AGENCIES TO PROCESS THIS SCENE.
IT IS NOT A SIMPLISTIC SCENE, AS
YOU CAN CERTAINLY UNDERSTAND.
WE NEED TO ESTABLISH IDENTITY,
WE NEED TO DOCUMENT THE ENTIRE
SCENE, AND SIMPLY STATED WE NEED
TO ANSWER EVERY SINGLE QUESTION
SURROUNDING EXACTLY HOW AND WHY
THIS INCIDENT OCCURRED.
AS THE GOVERNOR SAID, WE WILL BE
HERE THROUGH THE NIGHT, BUT
CERTAINLY THROUGH THE WEEKEND.
WE'RE NOT EVEN PUTTING A TIME
STAMP ON THIS AS TO WHEN WE WILL
COMPLETE THIS PROJECT.
WE'LL WORK WITH THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER'S OFFICE.
WE HAVE TO ESTABLISH POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATION AND THERE'S A
GREAT DEAL OF WORK THAT NEEDS TO
BE DONE THERE AT THE SCHOOL.
WE'LL TAKE AGAIN, VERY BRIEF
QUESTIONS, BUT UNDERSTAND THAT
THIS IS AN ACTIVE, ONGOING CASE
AND THERE ARE MANY THINGS THAT
WE CANNOT AND WILL NOT DISCUSS
AT THIS TIME.
YES, SIR?
>> WE'RE TOLD THAT THERE ARE --
FATHER'S HOME IN NEW JERSEY AND
THE MOTHER'S HOME --
>> THERE IS A SECONDARY CRIME
SCENE HERE IN NEWTOWN, THAT IS,
IN FACT, CORRECT.
THERE IS A AN ADULT DECEASED AT
THAT LOCATION.
I CAN'T DISCUSS ANY FURTHER
INFORMATION ON THAT AT THIS
TIME.
THERE IS ASSISTANCE BEING LENDED
TO US BY NEW JERSEY.
I DON'T HAVE THE DETAILS ON THAT
SO I CAN'T ANSWER THAT.
I'M SORRY.
YES, MA'AM?
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> I CAN SIMPLY STATE THAT, THE
INFORMATION THAT WE HAVE RIGHT
NOW THAT WE WANT TO PUBLICIZE
THAT THE SHOOTINGS DID TAKE
PLACE IN ONE SECTION OF THE
SCHOOL, IN TWO ROOMS.
OKAY, ONE SECTION AND TWO ROOMS.
THAT'S AS MUCH AS WE WANT TO GO
IN RIGHT NOW AS FAR AS LOCATION.
OUR PERSONNEL ARE DOCUMENTING
THAT ENTIRE SCENE AND WILL HAVE
LITERALLY EVERYTHING MAPPED OUT
IN THE FINAL REPORT, FINAL
INFORMATION WE'LL PRESENT THE
ANSWERS TO THOSE QUESTIONS.
BUT RIGHT NOW, I DON'T HAVE ANY
MORE DETAIL THAN THAT.
OKAY?
YOU HAD A QUESTION, SIR?
SOMEONE -- RIGHT NOW THERE IS
ONE SHOOTER.
BUT AGAIN WE'RE STILL LOOKING AT
EVERY ANCILLARY FACT AND
CIRCUMSTANCE RELATED TO THE
DECEASED SHOOTER AT THE SCENE.
YES, SIR?
>>-I DON'T HAVE THAT
INFORMATION, I'M SORRY.
TO BE DETERMINED.
I DON'T HAVE THE ANSWER TO THAT
QUESTION, EITHER.
THE NEXT STEP WILL BE THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER'S OFFICE WILL
CERTAINLY ASSIST US IN ANSWERING
A LOT OF THOSE QUESTIONS.
THE MANNER AND CAUSE OF DEATH OF
ALL OF THE DECEASED.
THAT'S IT.
THERE'S 26 DECEASED.
I'M SORRY.
ONE INJURY.
ONE PERSON WAS INJURED.
[ WERE THE CHILDREN IN ONE
CLASSROOM?
>> THEY WERE IN ONE SECTION OR
ONE AREA OF THE SCHOOL.
THAT'S THE BEST I CAN DO ON THAT
ANSWER.
I DON'T KNOW SPECIFICALLY HOW
MANY ROOMS ARE INVOLVED.
I WAS TOLD THAT THERE WERE TWO,
BUT IN ONE SECTION OF THE SCHOOL
BUILDING.
>> THE ADULTS --
>> EVERYONE WAS IN THAT SAME
SECTION OF THE BUILDING.
SECTION OF THE BUILDING IS AS
FAR AS WE WANT TO GO.
WE DID NOT.
THAT'S TO BE DETERMINED ONCE THE
POSTMORTEM EXAMINATIONS ARE
COMPLETE.
I'M SORRY?
20 CHILDREN, 6 ADULTS, AND THE
SHOOTER.
27 TOTAL.
THAT'S CORRECT.
>> 20 CHILDREN?
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
THAT'S AT THE SCHOOL ITSELF.
THEN THERE'S ONE MORE THAT WE
JUST ADDED A SECONDARY CRIME
SCENE, THERE'S A DECEASED ADULT
AT A SECONDARY CRIME SCENE.
YES, MA'AM?
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
TO BE DETERMINED.
THAT'S REALLY SOMETHING THAT OUR
INVESTIGATORS ARE GOING TO HAVE
TO LOOK AT THOROUGHLY AND
COMPLETELY AND THAT WILL TAKE
SOME TIME TO TRY AND ANSWER THAT
QUESTION.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
WE HAVEN'T ESTABLISHED ANY OF
THAT, MA'AM.
WE HAVE NOT MADE ANY POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATIONS.
WE'RE WORKING ON THAT.
THERE'S SOME PRELIMINARY
IDENTIFICATIONS HAVE BEEN MADE
BUT WE HAVE, AS I SAID, A GREAT
DEAL OF WORK.
THAT'S ONE THING WE HAVE TO DO
IS ESTABLISH POSITIVE
IDENTIFICATION ON ALL THE
DECEASED.
AND IT'S A TIME-CONSUMING
PROCESS.
>> DO WE KNOW THE AGES OF THE
VICTIMS?
RANGE OF AGES?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
IT WAS A K-4 ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> -- WERE THERE STILL SHOTS
BEING FIRED AT THAT TIME?
>> THAT I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW THE TIME SEQUENCE.
THAT WILL BE SOMETHING THAT WE
WILL PROVIDE.
WHAT I'D LIKE TO DO -- NO, WE
DID NOT.
WHAT I'D LIKE TO DO THEN IS TO
TELL YOU THAT THIS IS A
BRIEFING.
WE'LL BE BACK IN 60 MINUTES,
MYSELF AND LIEUTENANT FROM
NEWTOWN WILL BE BACK IN 60
MINUTES, SEE IF THERE'S ANY MORE
DETAIL.
I'VE GOT SOME OF THE QUESTIONS
THAT YOU'VE POSED.
I'LL SEE IF I CAN GET YOU MORE
ANSWERS TO PROVIDE YOU WITH
INFORMATION.
THAT WILL BE JUST ABOUT 20 TO
5:00, QUARTER TO 5:00.
THAT I DON'T KNOW.
>> 20 CHILDREN, 6 ADULTS AND THE
SHOOTER, IS THAT CORRECT?
>> 20 CHILDREN, 6 ADULTS IN THE
FACILITY, PLUS THE SHOOTER,
THAT'S 27.
AND THEN A SECONDARY SCENE WITH
AN ADDITIONAL ADULT VICTIM AT
THAT SECONDARY SCENE.
>> SO 28 IN TOTAL.
>> 28.
>> OKAY.
>> YOU SAID QUARTER TO FIVE?
>> 20 OF, QUARTER OF.
>> DO YOU HAVE THE NAMES OF THE
CHILDREN?
>> I DO NOT.
ONE THING I WOULD LIKE TO SAY IS
THAT WE HAVE BEEN MEETING WITH
ALL OF THE FAMILY MEMBERS.
IT'S A VERY, VERY DIFFICULT
SCENE FOR THE FAMILY MEMBERS,
FOR ALL THE RESPONDING FIRST
RESPONDERS.
IT'S A TRAGEDY.
IT'S A TRAGIC SCENE.
I WOULD -- WE'VE BEEN ASKED BY
THE FAMILY MEMBERS TO ASK THE
MEMBERS OF THE PRESS TO RESPECT
THEIR PRIVACY, AND TO PLEASE
LEAVE THEM ALONE AT THIS TIME.
THEY'RE GOING THROUGH A
TREMENDOUS AMOUNT OF GRIEF,
WHICH I'M SURE YOU CAN
APPRECIATE.
SO I WOULD -- I'VE BEEN ASKED TO
ASK YOU THAT PERSONALLY BY THE
FAMILY MEMBERS.
ALL RIGHT?
I'LL BE BACK IN 60 MINUTES, THE
LIEUTENANT WILL ANSWER ANY
ADDITIONAL QUESTIONS WE CAN.
>> LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE OF THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE THERE.
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THIS IS DAVID MUIR IN NEW YORK.
YOU'RE WATCHING CONTINUING
COVERAGE HERE ON ABC NEWS OF
THIS TRAGEDY THAT'S UNFOLDED IN
CONNECTICUT AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE'VE BEEN ON THE HAAIR FOR HOU
NOW.
HE JUST PROVIDED NEW
INFORMATION.
THE NUMBERS REALLY ARE
STAGGERING WHEN YOU BREAK THEM
DOWN.
AS WE ALL KNOW THIS WAS AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
IT'S GOING TO BE IN THE HISTORY
BOOKS BECAUSE THIS IS THE
DEADLIEST DAY EVER AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN THIS
COUNTRY.
18 CHILDREN.
2 AREAS OF THE SCHOOL.
WE DO BELIEVE THAT SIX ADULTS
ARE AMONG THE DEAD.
THAT WOULD BRING THE TOTAL TO 26
DEAD, AND THEN THE GUNMAN.
SO THAT'S WHERE THE NUMBER 27
COMES FROM INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
SO 18 CHILDREN, 6 ADULTS, AND
THE GUNMAN.
AND WE DO BELIEVE, ACCORDING TO
THE LIEUTENANT THERE MOMENTS AGO
THAT THERE'S AN ADDITIONAL ADULT
WHO IS DECEASED AT A SEPARATE
LOCATION IN NEWTOWN, HE SAID.
RIGHT THERE IN THAT COMMUNITY.
ANOTHER ADULT, HE WOULD NOT SAY
THE RELATIONSHIP TO THE SUSPECT,
THOUGH WE DO BELIEVE THAT THERE
WAS A RELATIONSHIP AT THE
SCHOOL, THE MOTHER, IN FACT, A
TEACHER AT THE SCHOOL TEACHING
KINDERGARTEN, HAS BEEN THE
BELIEF.
THE SCHOOL IS K THROUGH 4 AND HE
POINTED OUT IT WAS IN TWO ROOMS
OF THE SCHOOL.
ONE PARTICULAR SECTION OF THE
SCHOOL, 18 CHILDREN.
18 CHILDREN, 6 ADULTS IN THAT
SCHOOL, AND THEN WHAT HE DIDN'T
MAKE CLEAR IS WHETHER OR NOT THE
GUNMAN THE SUSPECT THEN TOOK
THEIR OWN LIFE OR WHETHER OR NOT
AUTHORITIES HAD ACTUALLY ENTERED
THE SCHOOL AT THAT POINT.
HE SAID HE SIMPLY DID NOT KNOW
THE ANSWER TO THAT QUESTION.
HE PROMISED, OF COURSE, TO COME
BACK IN FRONT OF REPORTERS IN AN
HOUR TO PROVIDE MORE AND WE'LL
BRING THAT TO YOU JUST AS SOON
AS WE CAN.
I WANT TO BRING IN OUR SENIOR
JUSTICE CORRESPONDENT PIERRE
THOMAS, WHO'S BEEN AHEAD OF THIS
EVERY STEP OF THE WAY FOR US
TODAY, PIERRE.
HE HELPED PAINT THE PICTURE
INSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
>> WELL, DAVID, THE SITUATION IS
STILL VERY FLUID.
WE'RE GETTING ADDITIONAL
INFORMATION.
FEDERAL LAW ENFORCEMENT SOURCES
WERE INITIALLY GIVEN THE NAME OF
RYAN LANZA, 24, AS BEING THE
SHOOTER.
BUT WE'RE BEING TOLD BY THOSE
SAME SOURCES THAT THERE'S SOME
CONFUSION NOW.
IT MAY, IN FACT, THE SHOOTER
MAY, IN FACT, BE HIS BROTHER
ADAM LANZA.
SO WE'RE TRYING TO GET THAT
CLEARED UP AS WE SPEAK, LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS SAY,
AGAIN, IT'S A VERY FLUID
SITUATION, AND OBVIOUSLY THE
SHOOTER IS DEAD AND THEY'RE
TRYING TO CONFIRM ALL THE
INFORMATION THAT THEY HAVE.
>> THANK YOU, PIERRE.
I'D BE REMISS IF I DIDN'T POINT
OUT THE TWO CHILDREN WHO WERE
TAKEN TO AREA HOSPITALS AND WHO
DIED AT THE HOSPITAL, AS YOU
REMEMBER, EARLIER IN OUR
COVERAGE WE REPORTED THREE
PEOPLE HAD BEEN RUSHED TO THE
HOSPITAL.
NOW WE'VE LEARNED THAT TWO OF
THEM WERE CHILDREN, AND THEY DID
NOT SURVIVE THIS.
SO IT'S 18 CHILDREN IN THE
SCHOOL, 2 CHILDREN AT THE
HOSPITAL, 6 ADULTS AT THE
SCHOOL, AND THE GUNMAN.
AND WHAT WE'RE TRYING TO LEARN
AT THIS HOUR IS THE OTHER ADULT
WHO IS DECEASED, AS WELL, AT A
SEPARATE LOCATION, A SECOND
LOCATION WHERE AUTHORITIES ARE
RIGHT NOW INVESTIGATING AND
WE'LL BRING THAT TO YOU JUST AS
SOON AS IT COMES IN.
I WANT TO GO TO A MOMENT THAT WE
HAD EARLIER THAT I WAS MOVED BY
AND I'M SURE IF YOU'VE BEEN WITH
US THROUGHOUT THE DAY, THAT YOU
WERE, TOO, IT'S THE LITTLE BOY,
HIS LITTLE SHORT HAIR, AND WHAT
HE FELT, WHAT HE SAW, WHAT HE
SAID WHEN HE WAS ONE OF THE
STUDENTS TO GET OUT OF THAT
SCHOOL AND THEN TURN ON BOTH
SIDES AND SAW HIS FRIENDS HAD
MADE IT OUT, TOO.
HERE HE IS.
>> THERE'S A MAN CAME DOWN WITH
HANDCUFFS ON AND WE THOUGHT THAT
WAS THE VICTIM.
WE DIDN'T GET A GOOD LOOK AT HIM
BECAUSE HE WAS LIKE THERE WAS A
CAR BLOCKING IT.
PLUS WE WERE RUNNING REALLY
QUICK.
SO THEN WE GOT TO THE FIREHOUSE,
AND WE SAT IN OUR CLASSES, AND
WE WERE ALL REALLY HAPPY THAT WE
WERE ALL ALIVE.
>> IT WAS TERRIFYING.
I'M STILL TERRIFIED.
I THINK I'M STILL IN SHOCK ABOUT
IT ALL.
I STILL DON'T KNOW EVERYTHING
THAT HAPPENED.
I KNOW THAT THERE ARE SOME
PEOPLE MISSING THAT THEY'VE BEEN
TAKEN TO THE HOSPITAL.
I DON'T KNOW IF EVERYONE'S BEEN
ACCOUNTED FOR.
IT'S TERRIFYING.
YOU KNOW, THE -- YOU'RE RUSHING
OVER HERE, AND YOU CAN'T GET TO
WHERE YOU NEED TO GO, AND YOU
HAVE TO PARK DOWN HERE, AND
WALK.
I'M GLAD THAT MY SON IS OKAY.
HE SEEMS TO BE HANDLING IT
ACTUALLY PRETTY GOOD RIGHT NOW.
I KNOW MY SON'S TEACHERS HAVE
BEEN OKAY, AS WELL.
BUT I'VE HEARD OTHER TEACHERS
ARE NOT OKAY.
>> ARE THERE PARENTS THAT STILL
DON'T KNOW IF THEIR KIDS ARE
UNACCOUNTED FOR?
>> THERE WERE A FEW.
THEY ACTUALLY FOUND, I THINK
THEY JUST FOUND ONE, THERE WAS A
BIG CHEER THAT WENT UP BECAUSE
THEY FOUND SOMEONE, AND THEY
JUST MAY HAVE BEEN NOT, YOU
KNOW, NOT AT THE FIREHOUSE.
SOMEWHERE ELSE.
>> THE NUMBERS ARE 27 PEOPLE.
>> GETS US EVERY TIME WE SEE
THAT FATHER PUT HIS HAND TO HIS
FACE, STANDING NEXT TO HIS BRAVE
LITTLE BOY, JUST TO THE SIDE OF
HIM WHO SAID HE WAS JUST GLAD
HIS FRIENDS GOT OUT, TOO.
I HAVE NEW INFORMATION TO BRING
ALONG TO YOU, WHICH HELPS TO ADD
TO WHAT WE HEARD FROM LIEUTENANT
PAUL VANCE THERE A MOMENT AGO
ABOUT WHAT'S HAPPENING INSIDE
THAT SCHOOL.
IT'S BELIEVED THAT HE SAID IN
TWO ROOMS, ONE SECTION OF THE
SCHOOL, AND IT'S BELIEVED THAT
THAT MOTHER, THE CONNECTION TO
THE SUSPECT, OBVIOUSLY, WHO WENT
IN TO THAT SCHOOL TODAY, SHE WAS
FOUND DEAD.
IT'S BELIEVED AND THIS IS
CONFIRMED WITH OUR SOURCES AT
THE DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE, THAT
SHE WAS A KINDERGARTEN TEACHER
AND THAT MANY OF THE STUDENTS
WHO WERE KILLED WERE IN CLASS
WITH HER.
SO SHE WAS KILLED.
IT'S BELIEVED MANY OF HER
STUDENTS WERE KILLED.
ACCORDING TO MULTIPLE SOURCES.
THE GUNMAN WAS ALSO A STUDENT
WHO GREW UP AND WENT TO THAT
SCHOOL.
WE'LL BE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE
DYNAMICS OF THIS FAMILY, WHAT
POSSIBLY COULD HAVE LED TO THIS,
BUT THAT IS GOING TO BE ONE OF
THE CLASSROOMS WHERE WE HEAR
ABOUT THIS, THE EXTRAORDINARY
HORROR OF A TEACHER, A
KINDERGARTEN TEACHER, AND ABOUT
THE STUDENTS INSIDE THAT CLASS,
AND THE PARENTS WHO MET WITH
GOVERNOR MALLOY, AND YOU HEARD
THE LIEUTENANT THERE SAY, PAUL
VANCE, SAY THAT THIS MEETING
WITH THE FAMILY MEMBERS WAS
EXTRAORDINARILY DIFFICULT, THAT
THIS IS A TRAGIC SCENE.
AND WE CAN ONLY IMAGINE AS WE
SIT HERE AT A DESK IN NEW YORK
ABOUT 45 MINUTES AWAY AS THAT
ALL UNFOLDS.
I DO KNOW THAT MY COLLEAGUE
CHRIS COMO THE ANCHOR OF "20/20"
IS IN THE REGION, SHADY BROOK,
WHICH IS A NEIGHBORING
COMMUNITY.
CHRIS, WHAT CAN YOU REPORT?
>> WELL, SHADY BROOK IS WHERE
THIS COMMUNITY THAT GOES TO THIS
TOWN IN NEWTOWN IS FROM.
IT'S A VERY SMALL PLACE.
WE'VE BEEN, TODAY, IN A HOME
THAT HAS BEEN FILLED WITH PEOPLE
WHO DON'T KNOW IF THEIR KIDS
HAVE MADE IT, WHO FIND OUT THAT
THEIR KIDS ARE OKAY, AS THEY GO
DOWN THERE IN THE THICK OF THE
CHAOS TRYING TO FIND THEM AND
THE PHRASE THAT WE HEARD WAS
REALLY RESONATED WAS THAT THIS
WAS SOUL SHATTERING WHAT HAS
HAPPENED HERE.
WHAT WE'RE GOING TO LEARN ABOUT
LANZA WILL WIND UP BEING
PAINFULLY FAMILIAR TO US, DAVID.
PEOPLE WHO BECOME DERANGED AND
THEY HATCH A PLOT AND THEN THEY
CARRY OUT THIS TYPE OF MADNESS.
BUT WHAT HAS REALLY
DISTINGUISHED THIS, WHAT WE'RE
REACTING TO, IS WHO THE VICTIMS
WERE.
THESE KIDS WERE SO YOUNG,
THERE'S SO MANY YOUNG KIDS
INVOLVED.
AND WE'VE BEEN TALKING TO THEM
TODAY.
THE BLESSING FOR THEM IS THEIR
INNOCENCE.
THAT THEY DON'T REALLY KNOW THE
MONSTER THAT WAS IN THEIR MIDST.
THEY WERE TOLD TO CLOSE THEIR
EYES AS THEY WERE RUNNING OUT SO
THEY DIDN'T HAVE TO SEE THE
CARNAGE THAT WAS AROUND THEM.
WHAT THEY DO REMEMBER ARE THE
TEACHERS, THE TEACHERS WHO, WHEN
THEY HEARD GUNFIRE, DAVID, PUT
THESE KIDS IN PROTECTIVE PLACES,
STAYED THEIR GROUND AND TOLD
THEM STORIES.
PLAYED GAMES.
IN THE MIDST OF THIS MADNESS,
THAT THEY WERE HEARING, THEY
KEPT THEIR COOL, AND THEY GOT
THEIR KIDS OUT.
AND IN A SITUATION THAT IS
ALMOST UNBELIEVABLY HORRIBLE, IT
IS AMAZING WHAT THESE TEACHERS
DID IN THOSE MOMENTS TO GET
THESE KIDS OUT.
IT IS ONE OF THOSE SITUATIONS
WHERE AS TERRIBLE AS IT IS, AND
IT IS ALMOST UNMITIGATABLE IN
ITS HORROR IT COULD HAVE BEEN
WORSE WITH THE REPRESENTENRY AND
AM NATION PIERRE'S BEEN TELLING
US ABOUT THAT WAS BROUGHT BY
LANZA TO THE SCHOOL.
TO LOOK IN THESE LITTLE KIDS'
EYES AND HEAR THEM TELL YOU WHAT
THEY HEARD, THAT THEY WERE TAKEN
TO SAFETY REALLY BRINGS HOME HOW
HORRIBLE THIS WAS.
BECAUSE OF WHO WAS TARGETED.
AND IT'S A DAY THAT THIS
COMMUNITY IS NEVER GOING TO
FORGET, SO CLOSE TO CHRISTMAS,
THIS LITTLE GIRL ELLA, FIRST
GRADE LIKE MY SON, TOLD ME SHE
WENT TO SCHOOL THIS MORNING,
WORRIED ABOUT HER CHRISTMAS
LIST, WASN'T TOO LONG AND JUST A
FEW MINUTES AFTER SHE ARRIVED
HER DAY BECAME WHAT WE NOW KNOW
AS ONE OF THE WORST IN OUR
COUNTRY'S HISTORY.
>> THAT'S THE THING, CHRIS, SO
MANY OF THESE CHILDREN WERE
HOPING JUST TO GET THROUGH THESE
LAST COUPLE OF WEEKS FROM
SCHOOL, WITH THAT INTERNAL
COUNTDOWN IN THEIR HEAD, KNOWING
JUST HOW MANY DAYS UNTIL SANTA
ARRIVES, AND YOU DRIVE THAT
POINT HOME, WE HEARD I'M NOT
SURE IF YOU WERE WITH US
EARLIER, CHRIS, BUT WE TALKED
ABOUT A FIRST GRADE TEACHER AND
WE'RE GOING TO HEAR ABOUT SO
MANY OF THESE TEACHERS WHO TURN
OUT TO BE JUST EXTRAORDINARILY
BRAVE INDIVIDUALS WHO SHOULD BE
APPLAUDED FOR THEIR WORK EVERY
DAY IN CLASSROOMS ACROSS
AMERICA, BUT PARTICULARLY ON A
DAY LIKE TODAY, WHO TOLD
REPORTERS AT THE SCENE THAT THE
KIDS WERE BEING SO GOOD, THEY
SIMPLY ASKED CAN WE GO SEE IF
ANYONE ELSE IS OUT THERE?
THEY WERE WORRIED ABOUT THEIR
FRIENDS.
AND ONE STUDENT SAID, I JUST
WANT CHRISTMAS.
I DON'T WANT TO DIE.
I JUST WANT TO HAVE CHRISTMAS.
AND THAT FIRST GRADE TEACHER
RESPONDED YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
CHRISTMAS AND HANUKKAH AND SHE
SAID, I WAS JUST DETERMINED TO
STAY POSITIVE AS SHE LOCKED HER
KIDS IN THAT BATHROOM, THAT
FIRST GRADE BATHROOM, AND THEN
THEY GOT OUT.
AS THE DETAILS EMERGE WE CAN
TELL YOU THAT THE WEAPONS THE
GUNMAN USED, INCLUDED A GLOCK
SEMIAUTOMATIC HANDGUN, A
SEMIAUTOMATIC HANDGUN IN
ADDITION TO WHAT LAW ENFORCEMENT
AUTHORITIES ALSO TELL US WERE
TWO 23 CALIBER SHELL CASINGS, A
RIFLE CALIBER ALSO FOUND AT THE
SCENE.
WE BELIEVE THAT THE TOTAL AT
THIS POINT WERE FOUR WEAPONS,
FOUR WEAPONS THAT THAT GUNMAN
BROUGHT IN TO THE SCHOOL, AND WE
NOW KNOW WENT TO TWO CLASSROOMS
IN ONE SECTION OF THE SCHOOL, WE
KNOW THAT ONE OF THE CLASSROOMS,
IT'S BELIEVED HIS MOTHER IS A
KINDERGARTEN TEACHER AND IT WAS
HER CLASSROOM, THAT SHE DID NOT
SURVIVE THIS, NOR DID MANY OF
THE STUDENTS INSIDE THAT
CLASSROOM.
AND WE HAVE MADE THIS POINT OVER
AND OVER AGAIN, AS WE'VE BEEN ON
THE AIR WITH YOU THROUGHOUT THE
DAY HERE TODAY, IS THAT YOU KNOW
WHEN THESE THINGS UNFOLD IN
THESE SCHOOLS ACROSS AMERICA,
THAT YOU WALK DOWN THE HALLWAY
AND THERE'S A DOORWAY INTO A
CLASSROOM, AND IF THERE'S
SOMEBODY EVIL IN THAT DOORWAY,
THERE IS LITTLE A TEACHER CAN DO
TO HELP SHIELD HER CHILDREN OR
HIS CHILDREN FROM GETTING IN THE
WAY OF THAT GUNMAN.
SO I WANT TO BRING IN DR. JEN
ASHTON WITH OUR MEDICAL TEAM WHO
IS WITH ME ON THE DESK.
AND WHEN WE LEARN ABOUT THAT,
THAT SHE WAS A KINDERGARTEN
TEACHER.
THAT THESE WERE 5-YEAR-OLDS IN
THAT CLASSROOM, AND THAT THIS
SUSPECT WOULD APPEAR AT THE
DOOR.
IT'S JUST CHILLING.
>> IT'S -- THERE ARE NO WORDS TO
DESCRIBE WHAT MUST HAVE BEEN
GOING ON ON SO MANY DIFFERENT
LEVELS.
YOU KNOW, AS A PARENT, WHAT THE
FEAR AND CONFUSION THAT THE
CHILDREN WERE EXPERIENCING, WHAT
THE TEACHER WAS EXPERIENCING.
THE MENTAL ILLNESS THAT THE
SHOOTER, BY DEFINITION, WAS
EXPERIENCING.
AND THEN, THE SHOCKWAVES,
LITERALLY, THAT GO OUT, FROM
THAT POINT, THAT GROUND ZERO ON,
AND LITERALLY THAT THIS POINT,
NOW, I THINK IT'S SAFE TO SAY,
ARE BEING FELT THROUGHOUT THE
WORLD, WHICH IS, HOW SOMETHING
LIKE THIS COULD HAPPEN, AND THE
ANSWER IS, DAVID, AND WE'VE SEEN
IT, UNFORTUNATELY, SO MANY TIMES
BEFORE, BUT THIS IS THE FACE OF
MENTAL ILLNESS.
AND UNFORTUNATELY, AT THIS TIME,
WE HAVE SO MANY INNOCENT
VICTIMS.
BUT OFTENTIMES, THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT WE HAVE, IS INNOCENT
VICTIMS.
>> WHAT DO WE SAY TO OUR
CHILDREN TONIGHT, JEN?
>> YOU KNOW, I'M TRYING TO THINK
ABOUT WHAT I'M GOING TO SAY TO
MY OWN CHILDREN.
I THINK THAT THE FIRST AND MOST
PARAMOUNT TASK OF ANY PARENT IS
TO REASSURE THEIR CHILDREN THAT
THEY ARE SAFE.
YOU WANT THE CONVERSATION TO BE
AGE-APPROPRIATE.
OBVIOUSLY THE CONVERSATION THAT
YOU'LL HAVE WITH A 5-YEAR-OLD
WILL BE VERY DIFFERENT THAN THE
CONVERSATION YOU'LL HAVE WITH A
15-YEAR-OLD.
AND I THINK THAT IT'S VERY
IMPORTANT FOR PARENTS TO EXPLAIN
TO THEIR CHILDREN THAT SOMETIMES
BAD THINGS HAPPEN.
BUT, AS WE'VE HEARD MANY PEOPLE
IN MANY MENTAL HEALTH
PROFESSIONALS SAY, FORTUNATELY
IT'S NOT THAT COMMON.
AND THEN I THINK IT'S VERY
IMPORTANT FOR THE PARENTS AND
CHILDREN TO EXPRESS THEIR
FEELINGS, TO SAY, I'M SAD, I'M
AFRAID, IT'S OKAY IF YOU FEEL
THE SAME WAY.
AND FROM THAT POINT ON, DAVID, I
THINK IT'S CRITICALLY IMPORTANT
FOR PARENTS TO INVOLVE MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS AS EARLY AS
POSSIBLE.
THERE ARE HIGHLY TRAINED AND
SKILLED GRIEF COUNSELORS, SOCIAL
WORKERS, PSYCHOLOGISTS,
PSYCHOTHERAPI
PSYCHOTHERAPISTS, PSYCHIATRISTS,
CLERGY, THESE PEOPLE ARE HIGHLY
TRAINED IN HOW TO TALK TO
CHILDREN AT VARIOUS AGES TO GET
THEM THROUGH THIS KIND OF
TRAUMA.
BUT MAKE NO MISTAKE, THIS IS A
PROFOUND TRAUMA, NOT JUST FOR
THOSE CHILDREN IN THAT SCHOOL,
OBVIOUSLY, BUT FOR CHILDREN
EVERYWHERE.
>> EVERYWHERE WHO ARE WATCHING
THESE IMAGES.
AS WE KNOW IN THIS DAY AND AGE
IT'S NOT EVEN NETWORK
TELEVISION, IT'S THE INTERNET
AND THERE'S REALLY NO ESCAPING
IT.
ALTHOUGH WE ASK PARENTS
OBVIOUSLY TO FLIP THE CHANNEL OR
MOVE THE KIDS ELSEWHERE IN THE
HOUSE AS THEY WATCHED THIS
UNFOLD HERE THIS AFTERNOON.
ANOTHER PARENT FRONT AND CENTER
TODAY WAS THE PRESIDENT.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SPEAKING FROM
THE WHITE HOUSE.
AND AS IS SO OFTEN THE CASE, HE
WAS MOST EMOTIONAL IN TALKING
ABOUT AN INCIDENT HERE IN
AMERICA, GIVEN THE FACT THAT HE
IS A FATHER HIMSELF.
SASHA AND MALIA AND WE ALL KNOW
THAT THE PRESIDENT AND THE FIRST
LADY HAVE WORKED TO KEEP THEIR
FAMILY, TO SHIELD THEIR OWN
DAUGHTERS FROM THE PUBLIC
CAMERAS, AND SO TO LOOK AT THOSE
IMAGES TODAY, AND SEE THE FEAR
ON THOSE FACES, TO HEAR ABOUT
THE KINDERGARTEN TEACHER, AND
THOSE