IN THE BAY AREA.
ON THE PENINSULA, A SERVICE OF
REMEMBRANCE GETS UNDERWAY AT
7:00 IN BURLINGAME.
WILL TAKE PLACE AT THE CHURCH
ON EASTON DRIVE.
>> SCHOOL':ú@w SECURITY IS ON MS
OF MANY RIGHT NOW WITH SOME
DISTRICTS RE-EXAMINING THEIR
PROCEDURES.
>> ABC 7 NEWS CHECKED IN WITH
THE MILLBRAE SCHOOL DISTRICT.
TODAY.
LEANNE?
>> WELL, CAROLYN, YOU KNOW THE
SCHOOL DISTRICT SAYS IT HAS A
SOLID SECURITY PLAN IN PLACE,
THEY HAVE BEEN TALKING WITH
PARENTS SINCE FRIDAY.
A TAILOR MIDDLE SCHOOL,
SECURITY MEASURES ARE UPDATED
RIGLY.
LOCKS TO EACH ROOM CHANGED
ABOUT A YEAR AGO, PROTECTING
THOSE INSIDE FROM AN INTRUDER,
NARROW WINDOWS ARE COVERED.
THE MILLBRAE SCHOOL DISTRICT
HAS FOUR ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS,
EACH OF THEM HAS AN EMERGENCY
SECURITY PLAN.
>> WE HAVE MONTHLY DRILLS AND
WE'RE NOT TALKING JUST ABOUT
FIRE DRILLS BUT WE ALSO DO
LOCK DOWN DRILLS AS WELL.
.Jx&LYY, POLICE IS
PRESENT DURING A LOCK DOWN
DRILL.
>> EVERY MONTH, THOSE DRILLS
ARE REVIEWED.
IS THIS ONGOING COMMUNICATION.
>> THE SHERIFF'S OFFICE WORK
WAS THE SCHOOLS VISITING THEM
ONCE PER WEEK.
>> I MEET WITH THE PRINCIPAL.
AND DETERMINE IF THEY HAVE
NEEDS WITH THE SCHOOL.
ON TYPES OF TRAINING AND
PROBLEMS THROUGHOUT THE
SCHOOL.
>> THE MILLBRAE SCHOOL
DISTRICT ACKNOWLEDGE
INTERESTED THERE IS ROOM FOR
IMPROVEMENT.
THE DISTRICT NOTIFIES PARENTS
IT WILL-#LA REVIEW, AND ASSESS Y
SURES AT EACH SCHOOL.
MANY PARENTS FEEL CHILDREN ARE
SAFE.
>> I DON'T THINK THERE IS
IS
SCHOOL.
WE WOULD BE SURRENDERING
FREEDOMS AND IMPACTING OUR
KIDS PSYCHOLOGICALLY IN A BAD
WAY AND THE COMMUNITY IN A BAD
WAY.
>> SECURITY IS SOMETHING THAT
WILL BE DISCUSSED, TEACHERS
DID WHAT THEY DO SUPPORT THEIR
STUDENTS.
>> AND SO WE'RE HERE TO LISTEN,
TO BE HERE IN CASE CHILDREN
NEED AN ADULT TO TALK TO.
>> AND THEY DID A LOT OF THAT
TODAY, NOW, OF COURSE SECURITY
SOMETHING THAT WILL BE
DISCUSSED DURING THE NEXT
SCHOOL BOARD MEETING THAT IS
GOING TO BE HELD ON JANUARY
14th, PARENTS ENCOURAGED TO
PARTICIPATE, I'M LIVE IN
MILLBRAE, ABC 7 NEWS.
>> LEANNE, THANK YOU.
PARENTS IN CUPERTINO COPING
WITH A DOUBLE LAYER OF EMOTION
FACING THE TRAGEDY AS WELL AS
A BOMB THREAT IN A SCHOOL IN
THEIR OWN COMMUNITY.
>> WE ARE UP TO DATE ON THAT
FRIGHTENING INCIDENT.
NOW, HOW PARENTS ARE
RESPONDING.
>> HAPPENING NOW, STUDENTS SAY
TEACHERS NAMED IN THE BOMB
THREAT WERE RETURNED TO CLASS
TODAY.
THE TEACHER IS TRYING TO HE
TROURN A SENSE OF NORMALCY
AFTERyQTñ THREATENING GRAFFITI S
FOUND ON THURSDAY.
DISTRICT ADMINISTRATORS SHUT
DOWN TWO SCHOOLS, AFTER
DISCOVERING SPRAY PAINTED
MESSAGES SAYING THERE IS A
BOMB ATMONTA VISTA[Jkt÷
SUBJECT WILL BE PROCESSED
THROUGH THE JUVENILE COURT
SYSTEM.
>> AND ABC 7 NEWS WILL
CONTINUE TO COVER THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY AS IT UNFOLDS, ABC 7
NEWS REPORTER LAURA ANTHONY
WILL REPORT LIVE ON OUR
NEWSCAST AT 5:00 AND 6:00 P.M.
YOU CAN FIND LATEST
DEVELOPMENTS ON OUR WEB SITE
ABC 7 NEWS.COM AS WELL AS OUR
FACEBOOK PAGE AND TWITTER
FEED.
>> NOW, SAN FRANCISCO POLICE
ARE LOOKING FOR ANYONE WITH
INFORMATION ON THE SHOOTING
DEATH OF A CONCORD HIGH SCHOOL
FOOTBALL PLAYER SATURDAY
NIGHT.
MONTREAL BLAKELY SHOT AROUND
10:00 IN THE BAY VIEW DISTRICT,
TAKEN TO THE HOSPITAL BY A
FRIEND WRAEZ PRONOUNCED DEAD.
BLAKELY WAS A SENIOR IN
CONCORD HIGH.
THE SCHOOL HAS MADE GRIEVE
COUNSELORS VAINL FOR STUDENTS
AND STAFF.
>> MOVING ON TO WEATHER NOW.
A REALLY SOGGY START TO THE
WEEK.
>> THERE IS WIDELY SCATTERED
SHOWERS AROUND THE BAY AREA,
NOTHING LIKE STEADY RAIN WE
SAW THIS MORNING.
THAT WET WEATHER CAUSED A
NUMBER OF ACCIDENTS AND SLOWED
COMMUTE TO A CRAWL IN SPOTS.
>> UMBRELLAS OUT TODAY IN SAN
FRANCISCO, HERE IS SANDHYA
PATEL, AND I GUESS WE'RE NOT
PUTTING UMBRELLAS AWAY JUST
YET.
>> SMART IDEA LOOKING AT LIVE
DOPPLER 7, YOU'LL SEE WHAT IS
LEFT.
THERE ISN'T A LOT LEFT.
WE'RE WATCHING A FEW LIGHT
SHOWERS SOUTH OF SAN JOSE
AROUND MORGAN HILL AND DWIL
ROY TOWARDS MARINA AREA, VERY
LIGHT RETURNS RIGHT NOW.Ft,D
THE RAINFALL THERE.
SIERRA NEVADA TURNING TO SNOW.
AND CHAIN CONTROLS NOW ON
HIGHWAY 50, STATE ROUTE 8 1K38
4.
80 JUST LIFTED CHAIN CONTROLS.
THERE IS A WINTER STORM
WARNING IN AFFECT.
WEST SLOPE UNTIL MIDNIGHT
TONIGHT.
SO SEVERAL INCHES OF SNOW
EXPECTED WITH POSSIBLE TRAVEL
DIFFICULTIES.
SNOW IS WINDING DOWN.
SHEER HOW MUCH RAIN WE'VE
RECEIVED.
22/100ths IN SAN FRANCISCO
PICKED UP OVER AN INCH IN THE
SANTA CRUZ MOUNTAINS.
15/100ths IN SAN JOSE.
23/100ths OAKLAND.
SANTA ROSEA, JUST UNDER A HALF
INCH.
LIVERMORE, 7/100ths OF RAIN.
WE MAY SEE THIS SYSTEM WIND
DOWN THERE IS ANOTHER SYSTEM
COMING.
I'LL LET YOU KNOW WHEN YOU
MIGHT NEED RAIN GEAR AGAIN.
>> SPEAKING THAT HAVE SIS TINL,
SANTA CLARA VALLEY IS BRACING
FOR FREEZING TEMPERATURES.
>> DAVID LOUIE JOINS US LIVE
IN SAN JOSE.
DAVID?
>> WELL, ALL LIS ON RIVERS
SUCH AS THE GUADALUPE.
THE CREWS ARE MAKING SURE
DEBRIS IS CLEARED SO RAIN
RUNNOFF WILL FLOW PROPERLY.
NOW AIR, THREAT OF FREEZING
TEMPERATURES TOMORROW NIGHT,
IT HAS POSED NEW PROBLEMS FOR
HOMEOWNERS AND FOR THE
HOMELESS.
A GOOD NIGHT AS SLEEP INWRé
WARM, DRY PLACE IS IMPORTANT
FOR THE HOMELESS WHEN WHETHER
TEMPERATURES -- WEATHER
TEMPERATURES NASTY.
>> WE SEE OUR NUMBERS
INCREASING DURING THESE COLD
WEATHER MONTHS AND WHEN
WEATHER IS, YOU KNOW, HARSH
OUT THERE NOW.
IT IS NOT BY NIGHT, NUMBERS
TEND TO FLUCTUATE.
>> EAC LIGHT BUILDERS RUNS
SHELTERS IN SANTA CLARA
COUNTY.
LARGEST HERE AT THIS CENTER
HAVE 250, BUT CAN TAKE IN AN
EXTRA 100.G]Vj
HOT MEALS ARE PROVIDED.
INTAKE DONE USING A LOTTERY
SYSTEM.
BUT THAT IS SUS AND SPENDED
WHEN THERE IS A WEATHER
EMERGENCY.
MARK WHEELER KNOWS WHAT IT'S
HOSTILE.
>> ALL IT TAKES IS A LITTLE
BIT OF RAIN TO GET CLOTHES WET,
THEN, YOU'RE FREEZING.
THERE ARE PEOPLE THAT DIE OUT
THERE.
IT'S SAD.
>> THE COLD WEATHERA1çqç SHELTES
ALLOW SHELTERS TO WASH AND DRY
CLOTHES, BLANKETS, TOWELS AND
SOAP ARE PROVIDED TO CLEAN UP.
VARIOUS CITY, COUNTY AND
REGIONAL AGENCIES ARE
PREPARING FOR POSSIBLE
FLOODING LATER IN THE WEEK
WITH A MAJOR STORM DUE ON
THURSDAY.
AND A POOL CONTRACTOR WARNS
PEOPLE WITH ROOF TOP SOLAR
SYSTEMS TO BE PREPARED FOR THE
COLD WAVE.
>> IF YOU HAVE SOLAR PLUMBING,
SOLAR FOR SWIMMING POOLS HAVE
YOU TO EMPTY PANELS TO MAKE
SURE THEY DON'T FREEZE.
YOU'LL HAVE LEAKS ALL OVER THE
PLACE IN THE SPRING TIME.
>> AND ANDY RECOMMENDS
HOMEOWNER WAS LANDSCAPING
ESPECIALLY FLOWERING PLANTS
COVER THEM TOMORROW NIGHT
BECAUSE OF THE FREEZING
TEMPERATURES IN ORDER TO
PREVENT FROST DAMAGE.
ABC 7 NEWS.
>> INVESTIGATORS SEARCHING FOR
A RAPIST FOLLOWING A SEXUAL
ASSAULT OF A WOMAN ON A
POPULAR HIKING TRAIL.
>> THE WOMAN SAYS SHE WAS
ATTACKED ON THE MEDRONE TRAIL
LAST WEDNESDAY.
OFFICERS POSTED WARNINGS IN
THE AREA.
THE WOMAN SAYS THE ATTACKER
WAS IN HIS EARLY 40s WALKING A
HEAVY SET MEDIUM SIZED DOG.
THIS PARK SERVICE SAYS HE
PULLED HER TO THE GROUND, THEN
RAPE SKMERD RAN.
>> SO-TO-SAN FRANCISCO POLICE
OFFICERS BEING HAILED AS
HEROES FOR SAVING LIVE OF A
NEWBORN BABY INTO IS
REMARKABLE.
THE OFFICERS RESPONDED TO A
CALL LAST WEDNESDAY WHEN
ARRIVING THEY FOUND AíN2cç BABY
BORN JUST MINUTES EARLIER.
THE BABY COVERED IN BLOOD AND
NOT BLEEJING.
THEY DECIDED TO DRIFT BABY TO
THE HOSPITAL.
AND CLOUD DROVE AND ANOTHER
GAVE HIM CPR.
>> WE WERE SLIDING AROUND
PRETTY G BUT YOU KNOW, IT
WORKED OUT, I GUESS.
>> THE OFFICERS REMEMBERS
CALMLY. HE ADMITS HE WAS
EMOTIONAL, CRYING.
BIB BABY NASH IS DOING BETTER
IN THE HOSPITAL.
HIS MOTHER CHASE FAISS CHARGES
OF WILLFUL CRUELTY.
>> A MAN IN SAN FRANCISCO IS
RECOVERING AFTER FIREFIGHTERS
RESCUED HIM FROM A CHIMNEY.
THIS HAPPENED IN A SIX STORY
APARTMENT BUILDING.
THAT IS IN LAUREL HEIGHTS
NEIGHBORHOOD.
THE MAN PULLED OUT AROUND
MIDNIGHT, INVESTIGATORS DON'T
KNOW WHY HE WAS IN THE
CHIMNEY.
THEY SAY HE WAS NOT
TRESPASSING.
CRUISE HAVE LOOSENED BRICKS
JUST TO GET HIM OUT.
HE'S EXPECTED TO BE OKAY.
>> IF YOU'RE LOOKING FOR AN
INCENTIVE TO TAKE CARE OF
CHRISTMAS TREE TAKE A LOOK AT
THIS VIDEO.
THIS STARTED WITH FLAMES THAT
SPREAD TO OTHER PARTS OF THE
ROOM.#%Té
THEN, THE CHRISTMAS TREE
CATCHES FIRE, YOU CAN SEE IT'S
JUST A FLASH POINT AND A
FIREBALL OVERTAKES THIS ROOM.
THE DEMONSTRATION WAS SET UP
BY FIRE OFFICIALS, IT'S
ESTIMATED 400 PEOPLE DIE EVERY
YEAR FROM FIRES IN THE US USE
AND TAKES ONLY SECONDS.
>> COMING UP ON ABC 7 NEWS AT
4:00 iPHONE 5 APPEARS TO BE A
HEAD IN OUR AFTER THE BELL
REPORT.
>> A BUSY DAY AT THE POST
OFFICE.
WHAT IS THE LAST DAY YOU CAN
MAIL HOLIDAY CARDS TO ARRIVE
BY CHRISTMAS?
>> TAKE A LOOK AT THE LIVE
DOPPLER 7 HD.
RADAR SHOWS MORE SHOWERS,
WE'RE TRACKING ANOTHER RAIN
MAKER COMING OUR WAY.
>> AND A LIVE LOOK RIGHT NOW,
AT SAN FRANCISCO SKYWAY.
YOU CAN SEE TRAFFIC IS LIGHT
FOR DRIVERS MAKING THEIR WAY
SOUTH TOWARDS PIN ANYBODY SLA
AND BEYOND.
IT'S A REALLY HEAVY CRAWL FOR
THOSE TRYING TO HEAD EAST
ACROSS THE BAY BRIDGE.
ABC 7 NEWS AT
>>> POST OFFICE DEALING WITH A
RUSH OF HOLIDAY MAIL TODAY,
MONDAY BEFORE CHRISTMAS IS
TRADITIONALLY THE BUSIEST DAY
OF THE YEAR, BUT SINCE NEXT
MONDAY IS CHRISTMAS EVE, THE
BUSY DAY FALLS TODAY.
IT'S THE LAST DAY TO GET FIRST
CLASS PACKAGES OUT TO ENSURE
THEY ARRIVE BY CHRISTMAS.
>>> INVESTIGATORS TAKING A
SECOND LOOK INTO THE DEATH OF
SINGER AMY WINEHOUSE.
OFFICIALS SAY THE CORONER WHO
DID THE FIRST INQUEST DIDN'T
HAVE THE PROPER CREDENTIALS.
A HEARING WILL BE HELD JANUARY
8th RULED THE DEATH WAS AN
ACCIDENTAL ALCOHOL DEATH
POISONING BUT THEY BELIEVE SHE
DIED FROM ALCOHOL WITHDRAWAL
SAY SHEG WAS SOBER FOR THREE
WEEKS BEFORE THE DEATH.
SHE PASSED AWAY AT AGE 27.
>> CELEBRITIES HIT THE RED
CARPET IN THE NAME OF CHARITY
AND ENGAGEMENT AND BABY NEWS.
>> A RECORD BREAKING WEEKEND
FOR THE NEW HOBBIT FILM.
>> LORD OF THE RINGS WAS A
HUGE HIT, NOW, NUMBERS SHOW
THE TRILOLOGY MIGHT BE BIGGER.
IT'S OPENING WEEKEND, THE
HOBBIT AN UNEXPECTED JOURNEY
TOOK IN $84.8 MILLION, NOT
ONLY IS THAT A BETTER OPENING
THAN ALL THREE LORD OF THE
RINGS MOVIES BUT THE BIGGEST
DECEMBER OPENING EVER.
SARAH DREW IN A COUPLE OTHER
TV STARS TOOK SOMETIME OUT OF
THEIR WEEKEND TO HANG OIT WITH
KIDS AT CHILDRENS HOSPITAL IN
LOS ANGELES.
IT WAS A SPECIAL WINTER
WONDERLAND SETTING OO. TO BE
AN A PLATFORM WHERE I CAN
PROMOTE ORGANIZATIONS LIKE
THIS AND CHARITIES LIKE THIS,
IT'S MAKING THIS WHOLE SEASON
WORTH IT.
>> NEW@]k÷ EPISODES RETURN JANUY
10th.
SINGER KELLY CLARKSON MADE A
BIG ANNOUNCEMENT THIS WEEKEND,
SHE'S ENGAGED HER FEE JAUNS
YEAH IS THE STEPSON OF REBA.
SHE WROTE I AM SO LUCKY, AND
WITH THE GREATEST MAN, EVER.
AND MORE GOOD NEWS FROM
HOLLYWOOD.
THIS ONE ABOUT ACTOR CHANNING
TATE YU. HE AND HIS WIFE ARE
EXPECTING.
THIS WILL BE THE COUPLE'S
FIRST CHILD TOGETHER, THEY
HAVE BEEN MARRIED THREE YEARS.
AND YOU CAN GET MORE HEADLINES
ON OTRC.COM.
I'M RACHEL SMITH IN LOS
ANGELES.
>> ALL RIGHT, COMING UP, YOUR
CREDIT CARD COMPANY MAY OWE
YOU MONEY.
>> ALSO HEAD COULD CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL TRAGEDY BE A TURNING
POINT IN THE BATTLE OVER
STRICTER GUN CONTROL?
JUST AHEAD, CALLS FOR NEW
LEGISLATION.
>> WHY THERE IS NEW OPTIMISM
WE MAY AVOID THE
AND...
TAKE CARE OF THEM,
YOU KNOW?
I FEEL LIKE WE'VE
COME FULL CIRCLE.
LIKE THAT!
THIS IS HOW
I'LL DO IT.
Sarah:
THERE YOU GO.
TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
FUNERAL SERVICES SCHEDULED
THROUGHOUT THEv;Np WEEK FOR 20
CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS KILLED
ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
TWO CHILDREN WERE BURIED
TODAY.
STUDENTS DISTRICT WIDE
RECEIVED THE DAY OFF.
THEY WILL RETURN TO SCHOOL
TOMORROW.
SURVIVORS OF THE SHOOTING MAY
RETURN TO CLASS THIS WEEK,
HOWEVER, NOT AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
CREWS ARE FIXING UP A MIDDLE
SCHOOL IN A NEARBY TOWN,
SURVIVORS WILL ATTEND THAT
SCHOOL TEMPORARILY THERE.
IS NO DATE SET FOR SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY TO REOPEN.
>> THE MASS SHOOTINGS
SKPUT OREGON HAVE REOPENED GUN
CONTROL DEBATE.
>> CALIFORNIA SENATOR IS PROM
YITSING TO REINTRODUCE THE
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN EXPIRED IN
2004, IT WAS A SAN FRANCISCO
MASS SHOOTING THAT LED TO THAT
LAW.
>> ABC 7 NEWS JOINS US NOW
WITH MORE ON THE DEBATE.
>> JULY 1, 1993.
A MAN WALKED INTO A LAW OFFICE
AT9Yúx 101 CALIFORNIA STREET IN
SAN FRANCISCO, OPENING UP WITH
A PAIR OF TECH 9 HANDGUNS.
MASS MURDER AT 101 CALIFORNIA
ENDED WITH A SHOOTER TAKING
HIS OWN LIFE, BUT NOT BEFORE
KILLING 8.
>> ONE WAS MY WIFE, JODY.
AND I WAS LEFT WITH A
10-MONTH-OLD DAUGHTER AT THE
TIME TO RAISE MYSELF.
>> STEVEN BECAME A GUN CONTROL
ADVOCATE, TESTIFIED BEFORE
CONGRESS, STOOD WITH SENATOR
FEINSTEIN AS A BAN WAS SIGNED
INTO LAW BUT A PROVISION IN
THE LAW ALLOWED TO IT EXPIRE
AFTER 10 YEARS, SENATOR
FEINSTEIN IS VOWING NOW TO ROW
INOWE PRODUCE THE LAW.
SAYS IT'S PAST TIME.
>> WE NEED TO TAKE A LOOK AT
WHAT KIND OF LAW WEZ HAVE TO
LIMIT THE FIREPOWER OF
PSYCHOTICS AND PEOPLE THAT
SHOULDN'T HAVE FIREARMS SO
THEY CAN'T HOLD MASS SHOOTING
AUTOS PROTESTORS MARCHED
OUTSIDE OF THE HEAD QUARTERS
IN WASHINGTON, D.C. THIS
MORNING.
IN BURLINGAME, SCOOT JACKSON,
AN NRA INSTRUCTOR SHOWS US
SOME GUNS HE USES TO TEACH
HOME DEFENSE AND PERSONAL
PROTECTIONS.
HE SAYS ASSAULT WEAPONS AND
HIGH CAPACITY AN ANYTHING
CLIPS ARE NOT THE PROBLEM.
>> KIDS ARE DETACHED.H]X#Ñ
EVERYBODY IS IN VIDEO GAMES.
THEY'RE DETACHED FROM PARENTS
BECAUSE OF THE MEDIA SOURCES.
>> JACKSON BLAMES VIDEO GAMES
AND A RELIANCE ON PRESCRIPTION
DRUGS TO TREAT BEHAVIORAL
PROBLEM AUTOS THERE ARE A
GENERATION OF MURDERERS BEING
RAISED BECAUSE OF VIDEO GAMES
AND MIND ALTERING DRUG AUTOS
AT SAN FRANCISCO LAW CENTER
THE DIRECTOR SAYS CONNECTICUT
DOES HAVE AN ASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN NOW.
>> CONNECTICUT, HOWEVER, DOES
NOT BAN LARGE CAPACITY
AMMUNITION MAGAZINES.
THAT IS SOMETHING WE
UNDERSTAND WAS USED IN THIS
SHOOTING.
AND UNFORTUNATELY, IT'S
SOMETHING WE SEE IN ALMOST ALL
MASS SHOOTINGS.
>> I DID CALL INDIVIDUAL YES
GAME PROGRAMMERS TODAY, AND
THEIR ASSOCIATIONS
ORGANIZATION DID NOT GET A
RESPONSE, COMING UP AT 6:00,
LONG TIME GUN RIGHTS MEMBERS
OF CONGRESS SPEAKING OUT
AGAINST THE CLIPS, WE'LL GET
REACTION TO THAT FROM OUR
FIREARMS INSTRUCTOR IN
BURLINGAME.
>> WE'LL SEE YOU AT 6:00.
>> A MEETING BETWEEN PRESIDENT
OBAMA AND TOP REPUBLICAN JOHN
BOEHNER AT THE WHITE HOUSE
TODAY IS GENERATING OPTIMISM A
DEAL ON THE FISCAL CLIFF CAN
BE REACHED BEFORE THE YEAR END
DEADLINE.
THE TALKS CONTINUED AFTER THE
HOUSE SPEAKER2v OFFERED HIKES9N
TAX RATES FOR EARNERS MAKING
$1 MILLION A YEAR, BOEHNER HAD
NO COMMENT AFTER THAT MEETING.
HOUSE MAJORITY LEADER SENATOR
REID BRIEFED CONGRESS IT
APPEARS AT THAT STAGE WE'LL
SEE IF ANYTHING CHANGES BUT IT
APPEARS WE'RE GOING TO BE
COMING BACK A DAY AFTER
CHRISTMAS TO COMPLETE WORK ON
THE FISCAL CLIFF TO GO OVER
ITEM AUTOS THE MEETING LASTED
ABOUT 45 MINUTES.
THE SIDES DO REMAIN FAR PART
ON TAX RATES WITH THE
PRESIDENT WANTING TO RAISE
TAXES ON INCOME EARNERS OVER
$250,000 PER YEAR.
>> CITY LEADERS WILL CONSIDER
A PROPOSAL TO DECLARE THE AIR
THERE A NO-DRONE ZONE.
THE COMMISSION IS WORRIED LAW
ENFORCEMENT WILL USE
TECHNOLOGY TO SPY ON CITIZENS.
VOTERS SET FOR TOMORROW.
AND AND SUPERVISORS HAD A PLAN
TOLSrET UP A GRANT ON
SURVEILLANCE DRONE.
THE SUPERVISORS AND SHERIFF
CAME UNDER PRESSURE BY PRIVACY
ADVOCATES INCLUDING AMERICAN
CIVIL LIBERTIES UNION.
>> RICHMOND CITY OFFICIALS
SAID TO MEET TO CONSIDER
PERMITS FOR REPAIRING THE
DAMAGED PORTION OF THE CHEVRON
REFINERY.
THE PIPELINE RUPTURED IN
AUGUST, CAUSING AN EXPLOSION,
HUGE FIRE.
THE CHRONICLE REPORTS CHEVRON
SAYS IT WILL HAVE TO LAYOFF
600 WORKERS BY THURSDAY.
THE COMPANY WANTS TO REPLACE
DESTROYED PIPE WITH A METAL
ALLOY.
CRITICS PRESSURING CHEVRON TO
USE STAINLESS STEEL.
CORROSION IS CONSIDERED THE
LIKELY CAUSE OF THE EXPLOSION.
>> CUSTOMERS OF THREE CREDIT
CARD COMPANIES CAN EXPECT
EXTRA CASH INCOMING DAYS OR
WEEKS.
AMERICAN EXPRESS, DISCOVER AND
CAPITOL ONE OWE $435 MILLION
TO SIX MILLION CUSTOMERS PART
OF A CRACK DOWN ON DECEPTIVE
CREDIT CARD PRACTICES.
>> THERE IS YOU KNOW, SHAKING
DOWN BAD BANKS AND THIS CARD,
GET SOME MONEY THAT, KIND OF
THING.
NOW, THEY'RE PAYING BACK.
THE MAN CAUGHT THEM, SOME
PEOPLE COULD SEE AS MUCH AS
$300 CREDITED TO THEIR
STATEMENTS.
>> CUSTOMERS NOT REQUIRED TO
TAKE ANY ACTION.
CURRENT CARD HOLDERS WILL
RECEIVE A CREDIT ON THEIR
J%
RECEIVE CHECKS IN THE MAIL OR
HAVE OUTSTANDING BALANCES
REDUCED.
REFUNDS SHOULD ARRIVE BIT END
OF MARCH AT THE LATEST.
>> WOULD BE NICE TO HAVE THAT
NOW.
>> YES. EXACTLY.
>> GO SHOPPING.
>> COMING UP A SNACKING
DISCOVERY COULD HELP YOUR KIDS
STAY FIT, AHEAD.
>> ALSO, RESEARCHERS
DISCOVERED BEST WORKOUTS TO
HELP YOU DROP THOSE POUNDS.
>> I'M SANDHYA PAT YES. LIVE
LOOK FROM OUR MOUNT TAMALPAIS
CAMERA. CLEAR SKIES, CHILL IN
THE AIR BY MORNING.
I'LL HAVE TEMPERATURES FOR
TOMORROW PLUS A LOOK AT WHEN
THE NEXT RAIN WILL ARRIVE,
COMING UP.
>> A LIVE LOOK AT TRAFFIC
THIS, IS THE VIEW FROM
EMERYVILLE BACK TOWARDS
McARTHUR MAZE THERE.
IT'S BUMPER TO BUMPER LEFT TO
RIGHT HEADING EAST TOWARDS
BERKELEY AND ON THE RIGHT SIDE
OF THE SCREEN MAKING A TURN
TOWARDS SAN FRANCISCO.
SLOW
You know how much Grandma
wanted to be here
for your fist Christmas?
You see
Grandma lives waaaay down here,
and you live way up here.
Brian, your cousin, he's
a little bit older than you,
he lives here, in Chicago.
And your Aunt Lisa lives here,
in Baltimore.
Uncle Earnie?
Waaay out in Hawaii.
But don't you worry,
we will always be together
for Christmas.
[ Male Announcer ]
Being together
is the best part
of the holidays
and Cheerios is happy
to be part of the family.
You just ate Dallas!
>>> CHECKING HEALTHY LIVING
NEWS A NEW STUDY REVEALS IF
YOU WANT TO BURN FAT, IT'S
BETTER TO HIT THE TREADMILL.
DUKE RESEARCHERS FOLLOWED 234
OVERWEIGHT ADULTS AND FOUND
AEROBIC WORKOUTS WERE BETTER
THAN RESISTANCE TRAINING AND
FOUND A WORKOUT COMBINING TWO
ACTIVITIES WEIGHT LIFTING AND
RUNNING WAS NO BETTER IN
BURNING FAT THAN RUNNING
ALONE.
RESEARCHERS SAY THE TRAINING
IS GOOD FOR YOU, AND JUST NOT
VERY GOOD AT BURNING FAT.
>> IF YOU CAN CONVINCE YOUR
DHOIRN EAT CHEESE AND
VEGETABLES AS A SNACK, YOU'RE
AHEAD OF THE BATTLE AGAINST
CHILDHOOD OBESITY.
CORNELLaPkb UNIVERSITY GAVE THE
KIDS A SNACK AND COMPARED THEM
TO KIDS GIVEN POTATO CHIPS.
THE NUTRITIOUS SNACK GROUP
ENDED UP CONSUMING 72% FEWER
CALORIES MEANING THEY FILLED
UP FASTER ON
>> CANADIAN RESEARCHERS SAY
WHEN IT COMES TO MILK, TWO
CUPS PER DAY IS ENOUGH FOR
TODDLERS.
RESEARCHERS STUDIED 1500
CHILDREN BETWEEN AGES OF TWO
THAT IF COW'S MILK CONSUMPTION
INCREASE SOD DID VITAMIN D,
BUT IRON LEVELS DECREASED.
RESEARCHERS SAY IT'S POSSIBLE
AND THERE ARE TWO FULL TO HAVE
OTHER FOODS.s:s'Ñ
A SHORTAGE OF IRON CAN IMPAIR
DEVELOPMENT AND SKILLS.
>> FROM MILK TO SEWEDDA, DIET
PEPSI TASTING SWEETER TO YOU,
A NEW FORMULA HILT SHELVES IN
A FEW TEST MARKETS.
THIS NEW FORMULA CONTAINS A
SWEETENER IN ADDITION TO THE
OLD ASPERTAME.
IT COMES AS PEPSI TRYING TO
REINVIGORATE THE BRAND.
PEPSI WILL LAUNCH A REBRANDING
CAMPAIGN NEXT MONTH.
FORECAST, RAIN IS GONE, BUT
COLD IS STILL HERE.
AND SANDHYA PATEL JOIN USE
HEADING INTO WEDNESDAY MORNING
LET'S SHOW YOU LIVE DOPPLER 7
HD NOW.
RAIN MOVED OUT OF THE BAY AREA,
WE HAVE SHOWERS LEFT BETWEEN
GILROY, DOWN TOWARDS SALINAS.
VERY LIGHT RETURNS AS YOU CAN
SEE HERE.
AND IF YOU HAVE TRAVEL PLANS
FOR TUESDAY, WE'RE EXPECTING
SNOW AROUND YOSEMITE.
37 DEGREES, TAHOE, SNOW AND 24
DEGREES.
SHOWERS, SNOW MIXING IN.
FREEZE WARNING FOR TOMORROW
MORNING 1:00 TO 8:00 A.M.
IT'S GOING TO BE COLD UP THERE.
LOOKING AT THE FORECAST,
PARTLY CLOUDY, COOL AFTERNOON
TOMORROW, MID-40s TO MID-50s
AS YOU'LL NOTICE THERE.
IS A SLIGHT CHANCE OF SHOWERS
FOR YOUR TUESDAY.
AS A COLD SYSTEM SKIRTS THE
COASTLINE.
REALLY DOESN'T LOOK LIKE A BIG
SHOWER EVENT.
WE'LL NOTICE THE CHILL IN THE
AIR HEADING INTO WEDNESDAY
MORNING.
TEMPERATURES DROPPING DOWN TO
FREEZING IN SOME BAY AREA
COMMUNITIES SO THEY MAY END UP,
NATIONAL WEATHER SERVICE
ISSUING A WATCH OR WARNING
GETTING CLOSER.
OF COURSE, MORE RAIN IS IN THE
FORECAST LATER ON.
>> I CAN'T WAIT.
THANK YOU.
>> ALL RIGHT.
HERE'S LOOKING AT YOU.
>> THE PIANO FROM THE FILM
KA -- CASA BLANKA. YOU'LL
RECOGNIZE THE WINNING BIDDER.
>> TO THROW A HOLIDAY PARTY ON
A BUDGET.
FROZEN APPETIZERS PUT TO THE
TEST.
>> BOYS LIKE TO BAKE, NOW
THEY'LL BE UP TO USING
SOMETHING THAT IS NOT PINK.
WHAT HAPPENED WHEN LITTLE
>>> A MAJOR TOY COMPANY
CHANGING THE WAY IT MARKETS
ONE OF THE POPULAR PRODUCTS TO
TRY TO MAKE IT MORE GENDER
INCLUSIVE.
EASY BAKE OVEN HAS BEEN A
FAVORITE FOR GIRLS FOR
GENERATIONS UNTIL NOW,
MARKETED ONLY IN PINK AND
PURPLE.
AFTER A 13-YEAR-OLD GIRL
STARTED A PETITION, HASBRO
AGREED TO MAKE IT TO INCLUDE
NEUTRAL COLORS.
SHE STARTED THE CAMPAIGN
BECAUSE HER 4-YEAR-OLD BROTHER
SAYS HE WANTS TO BE A CHEF.
>> THIS IS OF COURSE THE
SEASON FOR ENTERTAINING AT
HOME. AND CONSUMER REPORTS
PARTNERED WITH 7 ON YOUR SIDE
FOR THIS PROPERTY ABOUT HOW TO
ENTERTAIN FOR LESS.
>> MICHAEL FINNEY SWRIL DETAILS.
>> 'TIS THE SEASON TO
CELEBRATE WITH FRIENDS, FAMILY
AND FOOD UP AND GRADE YOUR
USUAL CHEEK AND CRACKER
APPETIZERS.
CONSUMER REPORTS FINDS CERTAIN
READY MADE APPETIZERS SAVE
TIME, AND MONEY.
>> WANT TO BE THE HOSTS
WITHOUT BREAKING THE BANK?
LOOK NO ARE FURTHER THAN THIS
CONSUMER REPORTS TESTED 18
FROZEN APPETIZERS.
IT'S EN INCLUDING STEAKS AND
PIE.
Fñ
AND TGI FRIDAY'S LEAVING A LOT
OF CHEESE ON THE TRAY.
OF THE SIX CHEESE STICKS
TESTED ONLY ONE TURNED OUT TO
BE VERY GOOD.
THE FARM RICH BREADED STICKS
WERE BIG CHEESEY AND TASTY.
>> OUR TRAIN TASTERS THOUGHT
OTHER SIDE WERE MEDIOCRE,
MINDLESS EATING.
ALL MOZZARELLA STICKS HAVE A
FAIR AMOUNT OF FAT AND
CALORIES.
>> THE LOWEST RATED IN THE
TEST CHICKEN TAQUITO.
>> THE BEST OF THE APPETIZERS
WERE ALL SIX TESTED, TASTED
VERY GOOD.
COSTCO ARE TOP RATED WITH
FLAVORFUL, FRESH TASTING
SPINACH.
ANOTHER GOOD CHOICE, THESE
SPINACH PIES SURROUND ROUNDING
FRESH TASTING SPINACH.
>> IT'S A GOOD THING TO BUY AT
THE STORE.
AND THEY'RE LOWER IN FAT AND
CALORIE AUTOS REMEMBER, A
LIGHT SNACK CAN HELP AWE VOID
OVERINDULGING ON APPETIZERS.
WHEN ORGANIZERS INDICATORORS
SUGGEST PLANNING SERVING EIGHT
APPETIZERS PER PERSON FOR THE
FIRST HOUR, THEN FIVE FOR THE
REST OF THE PARTY.
SERVING DINNER TOO, FIGURE
THREE TO FOUR APPETIZERS PER
PERSON.
>> NOW, WE'RE HUNGRY.
>> ONE OF THE HOT TRENDS OF
THE YEAR, PEOPLE DIGGING
DEEPER INTO THEIR MOBILE
DIGITAL WALTZ.
SOMEONE BOUGHT A $48,000
BULLDOZER TOPPING A LIST OF
HIGH END MOBILE PURCHASES FOR
2012.
46 THOI FOR A WHITE GOLD
DIAMOND NECKLACE, FOLLOWED BY
A RARE COIN COLLECTION.
CONSUMER TRACKER SAYS 13% OF
THE CYBER MONDAY PURCHASES
WILL BE MADE%kN A MOBILE
DEVICE UP AN ASTOUNDING 96%
COMPARED TO A YEAR AGO.
>> PLAY IT AGAIN, LEO.
WILL NEVER REPLACE PLAY IT
AGAIN, SAM, BUT ACTOR LEONARDO
DICAPRIO IS THE OWNER OF THE
MOST FAMOUS PIANO IN HISTORY
BUYING THE PIANO FROM
"CASABLANCA".
HE GOT A DEAL, EXPERTS THOUGHT
IT MIGHT BRING CLOSER TO $1
MILLION F YOU'RE A FILM
HISTORIAN, WE NOTE HUMPHREY
BOGART NEVER SAID PLAY IT
AGAIN, SAM, BUT SAID PLAY IT,
SAM.
>> STANFORD GRADS CAME UP WITH
AN INVENTION CHANGING LIVESFASqF
BLIND PEOPLE.
A PRODUCT IMPROVINGS AND
GETTING ATTENTION.
>> WALKING AND TEXTING.
WHAT A DANGEROUS PROBLEM IT
CAN BE.
>> I'M DAN ASHLEY IN THE ABC 7
NEWS ROOM.
COMING UP, REVIEWING SCHOOL
SAFETY PLANS FOLLOWING THE
SANDY HOOK SHOOTING TRAGEDY.
EVERY SCHOOL REQUIRED TO
SUBMIT A PLAN EACH YEAR,
YERKTS MANY DON'T THAT.
COULD SOON CHANGE Z INGREDIENT
BANNED FROM CHILDREN VACCINES
NOW A GROUP GIVES IT AN OKAY,
WHICH COULD IGNITE A NEW
CONTROVERSY COMING UP AT 5:00.
>> NOW, HERE IS A LOOK AT WHAT
IS AHEAD ON WORLD NEWS AT
>> TONIGHT WE'LL CONTINUE THE
COVERAGE FOR THE TRAGEDY.
WE JOIN IN THE SEARCH FOR
SOLUTIONS5ç: AND WHAT WE THINK
THE PRESIDENT IS GOING TO DO
FIRST.
AND ALSO, YOU'LL MEET PARENTS
COMING OUT OF THE SHADOWS
TONIGHT SAYING THEY THINK THEY
NEED HELP WITH THEIR CHILDREN,
TOO.
WE'LL BRING YOU THEIR STORIES
AND OTHER NEWS FROM OVER THE
>>> THE ACCIDENTS KILL 4,000
PEOPLE AND INJURE 60,000 MORE.
>> AND NOW, FOR SOMEONE BLIND,
PRINTED LABELS ON EVERYTHING
FROM SERIAL BCHL BOXES TO
MEDICATION MIGHT AS WELL BE
BLANK BUT A GROUP OF GRADUATES
IS CHANGING THAT NOW.
ABC 7 NEWS REPORTER EXPLAINS A
BUSINESS BREAK THROUGH IS
HELPING TO CHANGE THE LIVES OF
BLIND PEOPLE.
>> THIS IS A BAROMETER.
>> IT DIDN'T STOP HIM FROM
BECOMING AN ENGINE YEAR.
>> THIS THAT I COPIED AND
IMPROVED.
>> DESIGNING TOOLS MADE FOR
BLIND PEOPLE.
A T
CHANGES PITCH.
>> FROM A CARPENTER TO A
SODDERING IRON GARY ADOPTED
ALMOST EVERY TOOL EXCEPT ONE.
>> BLIND PEOPLE ZRONT A
PENCIL.
OR DIDN'T.
AND THIS IS UNTIL THE SIX DOT
MACHINE.
THIS IS A LABELER.
IT SPITS OUT A LABEL LIKE THIS.
>> DESIGNED BY STANFORD
GRADUATES THIS LABELER PRINTED
OUT STICKY LABELS IN BRAILLE,
A SIS TISM RAISED DOTS THAT IS
TAKING MORE THAN THREE MONTHS
TO LABEL ALL OF THE LITTLE
DRAWERS IN THE WORK SHOP WITH
SIX-DOT, HE SAYS IT WOULD TAKE
ABOUT THREE DAYS SO. BIG, NOW,
INVENTORS HAVE HIT THE
JACKPOT.
>> WE'VE BEEN IN THE RED.
>> NOT ANYMORE.
ROBERT AND OTHER GRADS JUST
ANNOUNCE AID COMPANY IS BUYING
THEIR START UP SKRKS BRINGING
THEM ON AS SENIOR STAFF
MEMBERS.
THE NEWLY FORMED LOGAN
TECHNOLOGY MAKES A DEVICE FOR
AUTISTIC KIDS.
AND PLANS TO START MASS
PRODUCING THE LABELERS.
>> THIS ISbg34v A GOOD FIT FOR
BOTH.
>> THIS IS BECAUSE IT ISN'T
JUST FOR BLIND PEOPLE.
BRAILLE.
>> IF YOU DON'T KNOW BRAILLE,
IF YOU KNOW A BLIND PERSON, OR
YOU WORK WITH A BLIND PERSON,
YOU CAN PRINT THEIR LABELS FOR
THEM.
>> AS FOR BILL, HE'S LABELED
EVERYTHING DOWN TO HIS
MICROWAVE OVEN.
>> THERE ARE THINGS LIKE POP,
POP CORN.
>> AND NOT STOPPING ANY TIME
SOON.
>> I'D LIKE TO LABEL THAT
CAMERA BEFORE YOU GET OUT OF
HERE.
>> MAZING.
>> THANKS FOR JOINING US FOR
ABC 7 NEWS AT 4:00.
I'M LARRY BEIL.
ABC 7 GIFT TO YOU IS A HOST OF
FREE APPS FOR SMART PHONES AND
TAB BLETS HOPEFULLY A LOVED
ONE WILL BE GETTING FOR YOU.
YOU CAN DOWN LOAD OUR APP FOR
iPHONE, OR TABLET AS WELL AS
KINDEL FIRE IN OR ABC 7 NEWS
APP AVAILABLE FOR THE DEVICES
AS WELL AS IPAD.
YOU CAN DOWN LOAD FOR FREE.
ABC 7 NEWS AT 5:00 BEGINS
RIGHT IF YOU.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
CALIFORNIA SCHOOL SAFETY PLANS
UNDER REVIEW FOLLOWING THE
SANDY HOOK TRAGEDY.
NOW, SCHOOLS COULD PAY IF THEY
DON'T NEED MEET A MANDATORY
REQUIREMENT.
>> I'M SANDHYA PATEL.
LIVE TRACKING JUST A FEW
SHOWERS NOW.
WHEN WE'LL SEE ANOTHER ROUND
OF RAIN HERE AND WHAT COULD
SETTLE IN COMING UP.
>> PEOPLE RUSH TO PROTECT
PIPES AND PLANTS FROM THE
FROST, THERE IS ONE ITEM
DEPENDING ON THE SUN THAT
OFTEN GETS OVERLOOKED.
>> GOOD EVENING, I'M DAN
ASHLEY.
>> SURVIVORS OF THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING WILL TROURN CLASS,
SOON.
>> BACK IN CLASS THIS WEEK,
NOW, SKILL TRADESMEN HAVE
DONATED THEIR TIME TO FIX UP
AN UNUSED MIDDLE SCHOOL IN
MONROE TOWNSHIP.
THE FUTURE OF SANLDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL REMAINS
UNDECIDED.
HEAD OF SCHOOLS SAYS THE
SCHOOL MAY SEE A RENOVATION
LIKE COLUMBINE HIGH SCHOOL SAW
AFTER THE 1999 MASSACRE.
TONIGHT SANDY÷
FUNERALS, MOURNERS TALKED
ABOUT LOVE OF ANIMALS AND
TACOS.
HE AND HIS TWIN SISTER
CELEBRATED THEIR BIRTHDAYS
LAST MONTH. SHE WAS IN ANOTHER
CLASSROOM AND SURVIVED.
>> NEWTOWN COMMUNITY BURIED
ANOTHER 6-YEAR-OLD BOY TODAY,
JACK PINTO ABC 7 NEWS IS LIVE
IN THAT DEAF STATED SMALL
TOWN.
THE YOUNG NEW YORK GIANTS FAN
WAS REMEMBERED TODAY.
LAURA?
HI, DAN.
I'M IN THE CENTER OF SANDY
HOOK HERE THIS, IS THE VILLAGE
THIS, IS ALSO BECOME THE
CENTER PIECE FOR A GROWING
PUBLIC MEMORIAL HERE AS YOU
CAN SEE.
THOUSANDS OF FLOWERS, STUFFED
ANIMALS AND FOLKS FROM AROUND
THE AREA AND COUNTRY HAVE COME
THEER PAY RESPECTS.
JUST A SHORT DISTANCE FROM
THERE IS A PRIVATE SERVICE FOR
A YOUNG BOY CLEARLY WHO WAS
DEARLY LOVED BY HIS FAMILY AND
FRIENDS.
>> AS THE HEARSE PULLED INTO A
FUNERAL HOME, FIRST OF THE
SERVICES FOR THE SANDY HOOK
VICTIMS WAS UNDERWAY.
AMONG MOURNERS FAMILIES WITH
CHILDREN.
MANY CONSIDERED THE ENERGETIC
FIRST GRADER AMONG THEIR BEST
FRIENDS.
>> HE LIKES TO PLAY AND STUFF.
>> SERVICES WILL BE CARRIED
OUT IN SIMILAR FASHION THIS
WEEK THROUGHOUT THE DEVASTATED
COMMUNITY.
THIS FUNERAL HOME HAD ANOTHER
CHILD SERVICE SCHEDULED FOR
TUESDAY.
>> FOR KIDS INSIDE, I MEAN, TO
SEE THEM GO THROUGH