>> THEY DID NOTHING TO DESERVE
THIS.
>> WHAT TRANSFORMED THIS HIGH
SCHOOL HONOR STUDENT, INTO A
COLD-BLOODED KILLER?
AND BRAND-NEW DETAILS FROM THE
HERO TEACHERS WHO SAVED SO MANY
YOUNG LIVES WITH THEIR QUICK
THINKING.
>> WE WERE COMPLETELY BARRICADED
IN.
>> I THOUGHT WE WERE ALL GOING
TO DIE.
>>> AND SUCH A SAD MORNING HERE
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
I'M JOINED BY ELIZABETH VARGAS
IN NEW YORK.
AND RIGHT BEHIND ME, THE SANDY
HOOK FIREHOUSE, WHERE MOMS AND
DADS CAME TO LEARN ABOUT THEIR
CHILDREN.
MANY SLEEPING HER THROUGH THE
NIGHT.
AND THIS HEADLINE FROM "THE
HARTFORD COURANT" SAYS IT ALL.
HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW RIGHT NOW.
THE SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA, 20
YEARS OLD.
HE ALSO SHOT HIS MOTHER BEFORE
COMING TO THE SCHOOL.
THE BODIES OF THE CHILDREN SLAIN
WERE STILL IN THE SCHOOL.
AND FAMILIES WERE NOTIFIED
OVERNIGHT.
THE NAMES WILL BE RELEASED THIS
MORNING.
YOU'RE GOING TO LOOK AT STILLS
FROM THE VIGIL RIGHT HERE IN
SANDTY HOOK LAST NIGHT.
A SCENE OF SO MUCH UNIMAGINABLE
GRIEF.
THERE THEY ARE RIGHT THERE.
THE FAMILIES, THE COMMUNITIES
COMING TOGETHER TO PRAY FOR
THEIR CHILDREN, THOSE WHO WERE
LOST TO REMEMBER THEM.
TRY AND COMPREHEND WHAT HAPPENED
HERE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
MY "GMA WEEKEND" COLLEAGUE, DAN
HARRIS, HAS BEEN HERE FROM THE
BEGINNING, COVERING THIS
TRAGEDY.
AND YOU WATCHED IT UNFOLD
THROUGH THE DAY YESTERDAY.
>> WE DID.
GEORGE, JUST WHEN YOU THOUGHT
THE MASS SHOOTINGS, JUST WHEN
YOU THOUGHT THEY WOULDN'T GET
WORSE OR MORE SHOCKING, ALONG
COMES ADAM LANZA, WHO BEGAN HIS
DAY BY KILLING HIS MOTHER, AND
ENDED IT BY STORMING THAT
SCHOOL.
AND OF ALL THE PEOPLE HE SHOT,
THERE WAS ONLY ONE SURVIVOR.
9:40 A.M., REPORTS OF GUNFIRE AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
>> SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
CALLER IS INDICATING THAT SHE
THINKS THERE'S A SHOOTER IN THE
BUILDING.
>> Reporter: ADAM LANZA WORE A
BULLET-PROOF VEST AND WAS
CARRYING THREE SEMIAUTOMATIC
WEAPONS INCLUDING A RIFLE.
>> I FELT A LITTLE SICK.
>> Reporter: WITHIN FIVE TO TEN
MINUTES, THE FIRST S.W.A.T.
TEAMS ARRIVE.
>> I NEED UNITS IN THE SCHOOL.
I GOT BODIES HERE.
>> Reporter: OFFICERS HELPED
TEACHERS LEAD SEVERAL HUNDRED
STUDENTS TO A NEARBY
FIRESTATION.
>> WHEN THE POLICEMEN CAME IN TO
GET US, HE TOLD US TO CLOSE OUR
EYES.
AND LIKE ON THE PICTURE ON THE
NEWS, DO THIS.
>> Reporter: AT 10:30 A.M.,
PRESIDENT OBAMA WAS BRIEFED ON
THE SITUATION, AS POLICE
DISCOVERED A SECOND CRIME SCENE.
LANZA'S MOTHER WAS FOUND DEAD.
POLICE SAY ADAM LANZA SHOT HER
BEFORE HE STORMED THE SCHOOL.
AROUND NOON, ABC NEWS LEARNED
THAT LANZA HAD KILLED 27 PEOPLE,
MOST OF THEM CHILDREN, BEFORE
TURNING THE GUN ON HIMSELF.
SHORTLY AFTER 3:00, THE
PRESIDENT ADDRESSED THE NATION.
>> I KNOW THERE'S NOT A PARENT
IN AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL, LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
>> Reporter: BY 7:00 P.M., THIS
LITTLE TOWN HAD SETTLED INTO AN
ALL-TOO FAMILIAR POST-MASSACRE
ROUTINE, WITH PRAYER VIGILS.
>> MAY GOD BLESS THE ADULTS WHO
LOST THEIR LIVES TODAY.
>> Reporter: OVERNIGHT, POLICE
ENGAGED IN THE HORRIFYING WORK
OF IDENTIFYING THE BODIES AND
THEN NOTIFYING THE FAMILIES.
NOW, THE BIG QUESTION IN THIS
INVESTIGATION IS WHY?
WHAT WAS THE SUSPECT'S MOTIVE?
GEORGE, IF PAST IS PROLOGUE, WE
MAY GET AN ANSWER.
BUT IT WILL BE DEEPLY
UNSATISFYING.
>>> LET'S GET MORE FROM
ELIZABETH IN NEW YORK.
>> ALL OF THE QUESTIONS, NOW,
ABOUT THAT SHOOTER.
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA.
AND NEW DETAILS ARE EMERGING
ABOUT HIM THIS MORNING.
AUTHORITIES ARE NOW INTERVIEWING
HIS FAMILY AND HIS FRIENDS,
TRYING TO PIECE TOGETHER WHAT
MAY HAVE PUSHED HIM SO FAR OVER
THE EDGE.
ABC'S BRIAN ROSS JOINS US NOW
WITH THE LATEST ON THAT PART OF
THE STORY.
BRIAN, ANY ANSWERS SEEM
UNSATISFYING AS DAN JUST PUT IT.
>> Reporter: HE WAS ARMED TO THE
TEETH WITH HIGH-POWERED WEAPONS,
THAT AUTHORITIES SAY WERE
LEGALLY OBTAINED BY SOMEONE IN
HIS FAMILY.
AND IN AN HOUR, ADAM LANZA WENT
FROM OBSCURITY TO INFAMY.
AUTHORITIES OVERNIGHT WERE
QUESTIONING FAMILY MEMBERS OF
THE 20-YEAR-OLD KILLER.
A MAN BELIEVED TO BE ADAM'S
OLDER BROTHER, RYAN, LEFT A
NEW JERSEY POLICE STATION, AS
AUTHORITIES SOUGHT TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT TURNED THE YOUNGEST MEMBER
OF THE LANZA FAMILY INTO A
MADMAN.
>> WE'LL GO BACKWARDS AS FAR AS
WE HAVE TO GO IN THIS
INVESTIGATION.
AND HOPEFULLY WE'LL STUMBLE ON
ANSWERS.
>> Reporter: FEDERAL AGENTS THEY
SAY RECOVERED TWO HIGH-POWERED
PISTOLS FROM THE SCENE, AND A
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE, CALLED A
BUSH MASTER, SIMILAR TO THIS
ONE.
BOTH ADAMS MOTHER AND FATHER
WERE LICENSED TO OWN SUCH
WEAPONS, ACCORDING TO FEDERAL
AGENTS.
>> THESE CRIMES INVOLVE PLANNING
AND THOUGHTFULNESS AND
STRATEGIZING, IN ORDER TO PUT
THE PLAN TOGETHER.
SO, WHAT MAY APPEAR TO BE SNAP
BEHAVIOR, IS NOT THAT AT ALL.
>> Reporter: EVEN BEFORE THE
SHOOTING, ADAM LANZA, SEEN HERE
IN A PHOTO TAKEN SEVEN YEARS
AGO, WAS KNOWN IN THE
NEIGHBORHOOD AS A TROUBLED
CHILD, WITH AN OVERBEARING
MOTHER.
>> MY SON PLAYED WITH HIM WHEN
THEY WERE YOUNG.
AND IN HER HOME, I KNOW SHE WAS
VERY PARTICULAR.
I JUST THINK SHE MAYBE HAD TOO
HIGH OF STANDARDS OR SOMETHING.
>> Reporter: ADAM'S FIRST VICTIM
WAS HIS MOTHER, NANCY, KILLED AT
THE FAMILY HOME, ACCORDING TO
POLICE.
ONLY THEN DID HE HEAD ACROSS
TOWN TO THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
WHERE AUTHORITIES SAID HIS
MOTHER ONCE SERVED AS A
VOLUNTEER OR A TEACHER'S AIDE.
>> THE CHILDREN DIDN'T HARM HIM.
BUT THEY WERE ASSOCIATED WITH
HIS MOTHER.
AND I MOTHER, I BELIEVE, MAY BE
REAL FOCUS OF ALL OF THIS.
>> Reporter: THE GUNS USED IN
THE ATTACK, ACCORDING TO POLICE,
ARE EXTREMELY POPULAR AND
COMMON, ELIZABETH, AMONG PEOPLE
IN THIS COUNTRY WHO DO OWN GUNS.
>> ALL RIGHT.
WE'LL HEAR MORE ABOUT THAT,
BRIAN.
>>> WE'RE GOING TO TURN, NOW,
FROM THE FOCUS ON THE SUSPECT TO
THE FOCUS ON THE FAMILIES.
GEORGE HAS MORE ON THAT.
GEORGE?
>> THANKS, ELIZABETH.
I'M HERE WITH LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE OF STATE POLICE HERE IN
CONNECTICUT.
KEEPING PEOPLE INFORMED ALL
THROUGH THE DAY YESTERDAY.
WE LEARNED OVERNIGHT THAT YOU
WERE ABLE TO NOTIFY ALL OF THE
FAMILIES.
>> OUR DETECTIVES MADE IT A
PRIORITY TO, IN FACT, IDENTIFY
ALL OF THE DECEASED VICTIMS, THE
CHILDREN, AND THE ADULTS, WITHIN
THE FACILITY.
>> AND WHAT MORE HAVE YOU BEEN
ABLE TO LEARN ABOUT ADAM LANZA?
WHY AND HOW HE DID THIS?
>> THIS IS SOMETHING THAT'S
GOING TO TAKE A SIGNIFICANT
AMOUNT OF TIME.
WE HAVE TEAMS PEELING THE ONION
BACK, SO TO SPEAK.
WE HAVE MANY, MANY QUESTIONS WE
NEED TO ASK AND WE NEED TO
EXPLORE.
>> THREE GUNS FOUND ON-SITE.
>> WE HAVEN'T DISCUSSED THAT AS
OF YET.
IN EXCESS OF THREE GUNS.
>> MORE THAN THREE GUNS.
WE KNOW ALSO THAT THE GUNS MATCH
GUNS THAT HIS MOTHER MAY HAVE
HAD.
HAVE YOU BEEN ABLE TO PUT THAT
TOGETHER YET?
>> I DON'T HAVE THAT INFORMATION
SPECIFICALLY.
>> DO YOU KNOW IF THEY WERE
OBTAINED LEGALLY.
>> THAT IS SOMETHING WE WOULD
ALSO EXPLORE IN THE
INVESTIGATION.
>> HOW ABOUT HOW ADAM LANZA GOT
INTO THE SCHOOL.
THERE WERE SOME REPORTS THAT THE
PRINCIPAL MAY HAVE BUZZED HIM
IN.
>> I THINK THAT'S SIGNIFICANTLY
PREMATURE.
WE DO HAVE A PRETTY GOOD IDEA
HOW ENTRANCE WAS OBTAINED.
WE HAVE AN ADULT WITNESS THAT
WAS WOUNDED THAT SURVIVED, WHO
WILL BE INVALUABLE TO US.
>> WHY THIS SCHOOL?
>> WE DO HAVE SOME BACKGROUND
INFORMATION, THAT THERE WAS A
CONNECTION TO THE SCHOOL.
THE SPECIFIC CONNECTION, I'D
RATHER NOT DIVULGE AND GET INTO
RIGHT NOW.
THERE'S A LOT OF DISCUSSION OUT
THERE.
>> HIS MOM MAY HAVE BEEN A
TEACHER THERE AT SOME POINT?
>> FOR OUR PURPOSES, IT'S BETTER
WE EXPLORE THAT CONFIDENTLY FOR
A LITTLE WHILE LONGER.
>> I KNOW YOU'VE SPOKEN BOTH TO
HIS BROTHER AND HIS FATHER
OVERNIGHT.
WHAT WERE YOU ABLE TO LEARN FROM
THEM?
>> WE'VE BEEN WORKING WITH LAW
ENFORCEMENT AGENCIES FROM OTHER
STATES, WHO ARE WORKING WITH US
ON THIS CASE, TO ASSIST US.
AND THEY HAVE EXTRACTED AND
OBTAINED INFORMATION THAT WAS
CRITICAL TO OUR INVESTIGATION.
>> ANY INDICATION THAT HE HAD
THREATENED TO KILL BEFORE?
>> THERE IS NO INDICATION THAT
SURFACED IMMEDIATELY.
THERE'S NONE WHATSOEVER.
>> ARE YOU CONFIDENT THAT HE
ACTACT
ED ABSOLUTELY ALONE?
>> YEAH.
>> LIEUTENANT VANCE, THANK YOU
FOR YOUR TIME.
>>> AS WE JUST HEARD, THE NAMES
OF THE VICTIMS WILL BE RELEASED
LATER THIS MORNING, INCLUDING
ALL THOSE CHILDREN.
PRAYING FOR THEM LAST NIGHT,
THIS COMMUNITY, HUNDREDS PACKED
INTO CHURCHES.
WE'RE GOING TO GO TO AMY ROBACH
WHO HAS MORE ON THE VICTIMS.
YOU WERE AT THE HOSPITAL ALL DAY
YESTERDAY.
>> IT HAS BEEN A DIFFICULT SCENE
FOR EVERYONE INVOLVED, FROM THE
FIRST RESPONDERS TO THE
FIREFIGHTERS.
IT'S ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE TO
IMAGINE THE HORRIFIC REALITY
THAT SO MANY PEOPLE ARE WAKING
UP TO THIS MORNING.
THAT WHAT HAPPENED HERE LESS
THAN 24 HOURS AGO, ACTUALLY
HAPPENED.
AND THIS MORNING, WE ARE
LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE TEACHERS
AND THE CHILDREN INSIDE THAT
SCHOOL, WHO SO TRAGICALLY LOST
THEIR LIVES.
DISTRAUGHT FAMILY AND FRIENDS
CAME TOGETHER TO MOURN, TO CRY
AND TO REMEMBER THE 27 LIVES
LOST HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> I'M SO SORRY.
>> Reporter: OVERNIGHT, WE
LEARNED FROM THOSE LOST, AMONG
THEM, 47-YEAR-OLD DAWN.
AND VICTY SOTO, A FIRST GRADE
TEACHER, WHOSE FIRST INSTINCT
WAS TO PROTECT HER STUDENTS,
THROWING HERSELF IN THE LINE OF
FIRE.
20 OF 27 VICTIMS WERE STUDENTS
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
20 CHILDREN.
AND NOW, 20 FAMILIES MOURN
PRECIOUS LIVES LOST TOO SOON.
>> THIS SCOURING EVENT, WILL BE
WITH US AND THEM FOR YEARS AND
YEARS TO COME.
>> Reporter: AND ACROSS THE
COUNTRY, AMERICA MOURNS.
AS PARENTS TRY TO EXPLAIN HOW A
NIGHTMARE BECAME A REALITY.
YOU KNOW, YOUR CHILD DOES NOT
HAVE HAVE TO BEEN AT THE SCENE
OF THIS TRAGEDY TO BE
TRAUMATIZED.
SEEING OR HEARING THE IMAGES ON
THE SCREEN ARE TRAUMATIC ENOUGH.
IF YOU HAVE AN OLDER CHILD, MAKE
SURE YOU'RE TALKING TO THEM
ABOUT HOW THEY'RE FEELING.
GEORGE?
>> OKAY, AMY, THANKS.
>>> I'M HERE, NOW, WITH JAMES
WILLSIE, THE COUSIN OF ANOTHER
VICTIM AND A HERO, VICKI SOTO, A
TEACHER AT THE SCHOOL.
I'M SO SORRY FOR YOUR LOSS.
YOUR COUSIN, FROM WHAT WE KNOW,
DID EVERYTHING SHE COULD TO SAVE
THE LIVES OF SOME KIDS.
>> YES.
FROM WHAT WE'VE BEEN TOLD, MY
COUSIN, VICKI, AND HER FIRST
GRADE CLASSROOM, TOOK HER
STUDENTS AND HUDDLED THEM INTO A
CLOSET.
AND THEN, SHIELDED THE CHILDREN
IN THE CLOSET, TRYING TO PROTECT
THEM FROM BULLETS.
>> PUT HERSELF BETWEEN THE
GUNMAN AND THE KIDS.
>> YES.
SHE'S DEFINITELY A HERO.
HER LIFE DREAM WAS TO BE A
TEACHER.
AND HER INSTINCTS KICKED IN.
AND PROTECTED HER CHILDREN FROM
THE HARM THAT WAS COMING.
I'M SURE SHE HEARD WHAT WAS
GOING ON.
AND WENT INTO LOCKDOWN MODE.
TOOK HER KIDS, PUT THEM IN THE
CLOSET.
AND BY DOING SO, SHE LOST HER
LIFE PROTECTING THOSE LITTLE
ONES.
>> WHAT HAVE YOU BEEN ABLE TO
LEARN FROM THE POLICE OR OTHERS
ON THE SCENE?
>> JUST THAT SHE WAS A HERO.
THE WAY THAT SHE WAS FOUND,
HUDDLED OVER HER CHILDREN.
HER STUDENTS PROTECTING THEM.
YOU KNOW, DOING INSTINCTIVELY
WHAT SHE KNEW WOULD BE THE RIGHT
THING TO DO.
>> AND SHE'LL ALWAYS BE
REMEMBERED AS A HERO.
WHAT ELSE DO YOU WANT PEOPLE TO
KNOW ABOUT YOUR COUSIN?
>> I WAS PROUD TO KNOW HER.
AND I KNOW THAT HER MOM AND DAD
HAVE PEACE KNOWING THE WAY VICKI
WAS TAKEN FROM US TRAGICALLY,
PROTECTING THE CHILDREN.
HER LIFE DREAM WAS TO BE A
TEACHER.
AND SHE WAS ALL ABOUT MOLDING
THOSE YOUNG MINDS.
>> SO, SHE LOVED IT.
>> IT'S WHAT SHE LOVED TO DO.
AND KNOWING THAT UNFORTUNATELY
SHE LOST HER LIFE.
BUT KNOWING THE WAY SHE LOST IT.
WE'RE PROUD TO CALL HER FAMILY.
AND THAT SHE WAS A HERO.
TRYING TO PROTECT THOSE
CHILDREN.
>> ALL OUR THOUGHTS AND ALL OUR
PRAYERS THIS MORNING.
>> THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>>> VICKI SOTO A HERO.
I WANT TO GO TO JOSH ELLIOTT WHO
HAS THE STORIES OF SO MANY WHO
DID THE RIGHT THING IN THE
HARDEST CIRCUMSTANCES.
JOSH?
>> I'M STANDING OUTSIDE A CHURCH
WHERE ALL THOSE LOST YESTERDAY
WERE REMEMBERED.
AND THEY WILL NOW BE PERMANENT
SCARS FOR THIS COMMUNITY.
BUT TO YOUR POINT, THERE ARE SO
MANY INSPIRING TALES OF HEROISM,
FOR ALL OF THOSE TEACHERS WHO
PUT THEIR OWN SAFETY AT RISK, TO
PROTECT THEIR STUDENTS, TO THE
STUDENTS THEMSELVES.
SO COMPOSED IN THE FACE OF SUCH
UNIMAGINABLE HORROR.
HERE ARE THEIR STORIES.
AMID THE ANGUISH AND TRAGEDY AND
AGONY OF THE SHOOTING AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY, WERE INCREDIBLE
ACTS OF HEROISM.
>> I THOUGHT WE WERE ALL GOING
TO DIE.
>> Reporter: FIRST GRADE TEACHER
KAITLIN ROIG TOLD DIANE SAWYER,
SHE PUT HER CLASS IN A BATHROOM.
>> WE HAVE TO BE ABSOLUTELY
QUIET.
THERE ARE BAD GUYS OUT THERE
NOW.
WE HAVE TO WAIT FOR THE GOOD
GUYS.
>> Reporter: DOWN THE HALL, THE
THIRD GRADE CLASS HEARD THE
GUNSHOTS OVER THE SCHOOL'S
INTERCOM.
>> SHE LOCKED THE DOOR.
AND PUT A PIECE OF WHITE TAPE
OVER THE WINDOW OF THE DOOR.
AND SHE TOLD US TO GO IN THE
CORNER.
>> Reporter: PREGNANT AND DUE
WITH A BABY ANY DAY, SHE TRIED
TO KEEP HER CLASS CALM.
>> WE KEPT HEARING GUN NOISES.
AND PUT YOUR HANDS UP.
AND WE JUST KEPT HEARING THAT.
>> Reporter: WHAT IS SHE SAYING
TO YOU?
>> SHE IS JUST SAYING, IT'S
GOING TO BE OKAY.
JUST BE QUIET.
>> Reporter: WERE YOUR FRIENDS
AND CLASSMATES DOING AT THIS
POINT?
>> WE WERE IN THE CORNER, ALL
CROUCHED IN.
AND ALL THE GIRLS WERE TRYING.
A COUPLE OF BOYS.
AND THE BOYS WERE LIKE, THEY HAD
THEIR EYES WIDE-OPEN, WATCHING
EVERYTHING.
>> DID YOU HEAR YOUR PRINCIPAL
SAY ANYTHING?
>> YEAH.
SHE WAS CRYING.
AND I THOUGHT SHE WAS SCREAMING.
THAT'S WHAT WE HEARD OVER THE
LOUD SPEAKER.
WE HEARD KIDS CRYING.
>> Reporter: WHILE PARENTS
RUSHED TO THE SCHOOL, DESPERATE
TO FIND THEIR CHILDREN.
AS A PARENT, WHAT MUST THOSE
MOMENTS HAVE BEEN LIKE?
IT'S HORRIFYING.
YOU ALWAYS WORRY ABOUT YOUR
KIDS.
BUT IT'S SOMETHING THAT YOU CAN
NEVER THINK WOULD ACTUALLY EVER
HAPPEN.
YOU NEVER REALLY ARE PREPARED.
>> Reporter: DO YOU WORRY ABOUT
GOING BACK TO SCHOOL?
>> YEAH.
I DON'T WANT TO.
>> Reporter: WHAT DO YOU WANT TO
SAY TO HER?
>> I WANT TO THANK YOU FOR
SAVING MY LIFE.
THERE ARE 19 PEOPLE IN OUR
CLASS.
AND SHE SAVED ALL OF US.
>> NOW, THERE WERE SO MANY
DISCUSSIONS ON SOCIAL MEDIA
YESTERDAY, ABOUT THE PROPRIETITY
OF TALKING TO THE CHILDREN OF
THIS TRAGEDY.
AS OUR DR. BESSER SAYS ABOUT A
TRAGEDY SUCH AS THIS, IT'S MORE
IMPORTANT TO KNOW YOUR CHILD.
AND TO THAT END, LITTLE TORI'S
PARENTS WANTED HER TO TALK ABOUT
THIS.
AND ONE FINAL NOTE OF HEROISM,
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, THE PRINCIPAL
THAT WAS KILLED IN THE ATTACK,
DID MANAGE TO TURN ON THE
INTERCOM BEFORE THAT HAPPENED.
IT IS BELIEVED THAT THIS WAS A
FINAL ACT OF HEROISM ON HER PART
TO WARN THE TEACHERS AND
STUDENTS OF WHAT WAS TO COME.
GEORGE?
>>> I'M HERE WITH MONSENIOR
ROBERT WEISS.
I KNOW YOU SPENT A LOT OF TIME
WITH THE FAMILIES IN THAT
FIREHOUSE.
HOW ARE THEY DOING?
>> WE WENT TO THEIR HOMES EARLY
THIS MORNING TO CONFIRM THE
DEATH OF THEIR CHILDREN.
IT WAS JUST HORRIBLE.
THE UNCERTAINTY, EVEN THOUGH
THEY KNEW IN THEIR HEARTS THIS
WAS REAL.
AND THE QUESTIONS THEY WERE
ASKING, THE REGRETS THEY HAD.
WHY DID I SEND MY CHILD TO
SCHOOL TODAY?
AND THE PARENTS ARE SHARING THE
LAST MOMENTS THEY HAD WITH THEIR
CHILDREN.
ONE OF THE DADS SHARED HOW FOR
SOME REASON THE CHILD GOT UP
EARLY AND JUST CAME DOWN AND
TOLD THE FATHER HOW MUCH SHE
LOVED HIM.
AND ANOTHER ONE SAID JUST THE
DAY BEFORE, THE CHILD ASKED HIM,
WHAT IS DYING LIKE?
SO, PARENTS ARE GOING THROUGH A
TREMENDOUS AMOUNT OF PAIN AND
HURT, DEALING WITH NOT JUST
THEIR PERSONAL LOSS, OR WHAT
HAPPENED TO THEIR CHILD IN THE
LAST MOMENTS OF THEIR LIFE.
>> AND THEY FOUND OUT FOR SURE
ONLY EARLY THIS MORNING?
>> EARLY THIS MORNING.
WE WERE GATHERED UNTIL AFTER
MIDNIGHT.
AND WE WERE SENT OUT WITH TEAMS
TO GO TO THE FAMILIES OF THE
VICTIMS.
>> HOW DO YOU CONSOLE A MOTHER
LIKE THIS?
>> WE MET WITH PEOPLE FROM OUR
PARISH.
IT'S JUST SETTLING IN NOW.
THE HURT AND THE ANGUISH.
AND THIS PART OF THEIR LIFE IS
GONE FOR THEM.
>> AND SO MANY OF THESE FAMILIES
ARE PART OF YOUR PARISH.
>> THE NUMBER OF THESE FAMILIES
ARE MEMBERS OF OUR PARISH
COMMUNITY.
>> SO, YOU BAPTIZED THESE KIDS?
>> I HAVE BAPTIZED A COUPLE OF
THEM.
SOME OF THEM WENT TO OUR NURSERY
SCHOOL.
SOME ATTEND RELIGION EDUCATION
AT OUR PARISH, PREPARING FOR
FIRST HOLY COMMUNION.
IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE THAT THESE
LITTLE CHILDREN ARE GONE.
>> WHEN THE FAMILIES TURN TO YOU
AND SAY WHY?
>> RIGHT.
THERE'S NO ANSWER TO THAT
QUESTION.
THIS WAS NOT GOD'S PLAN.
THAT WAS A MAN WHO HAS SERIOUS
ISSUES IN HIS LIFE.
WHY DO YOU WANT TO DESTROY
INNOCENT CHILDREN?
I CAN'T FIGURE OUT.
THAT'S THE QUESTION THAT PEOPLE
ASK AT THAT TIME LIKE THIS.
AND NO ANSWER COMES BACK TO
THEM.
>> MONSIGNOR, THANK YOU FOR
JOINING US THIS MORNING.
WE'RE GRIEVING WITH YOU.
>> I APPRECIATE IT.
I'M SO TIRED.
JUST BRUTAL.
>> THAT WAS TAPED JUST BEFORE
THE SHOW.
ELIZABETH, YOU SEE THERE IS SO
MUCH PAIN IN THIS COMMUNITY
RIGHT NOW.
>> SO MUCH PAIN.
AND THANK GOODNESS FOR PEOPLE
LIKE THAT MONSIGNOR, WHO ARE
HELPING THESE FAMILIES.
IT'S UNBELIEVABLE TO THINK WHAT
THE PARENTS ARE GOING THROUGH
RIGHT NOW.
THIS TRAGEDY IS REVERBERATING
AROUND THE COUNTRY ON SOCIAL
MEDIA.
BIANNA GOLODRYGA HAS BEEN
TRACKING THE LATEST.
PEOPLE ARE DEBATING EVERYTHING
FROM POSSIBLE MOTIVES FROM THIS
MADMAN TO GUN CONTROL.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
GOOD MORNING, ELIZABETH.
THERE'S NO WAY TO PREPARE
YOURSELF FOR SUCH A HORRIFIC
TRAGEDY.
ESPECIALLY WHEN THE VICTIMS ARE
THE MOST INNOCENT AND PRECIOUS
MEMBERS OF OUR SOCIETY.
AS AMERICANS BEGIN THE PAINFUL
CONVERSATION, TRYING TO MAKE
SENSE OF ALL OF THIS, MANY
TAKING TO SOCIAL MEDIA SITES
LIKE FACEBOOK AND TWITTER.
FROM SORROW TO OUTRAGE TO
COMPLETE SHOCK.
THIS MORNING, THE MASSACRE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, IS
SPARKING AN IMPASSIONED DIALOGUE
ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
>> IT'S HORRIBLE THAT SUCH EVIL
EXISTS.
BUT THAT'S THE NATURE OF THE
WORLD WE LIVE IN, I GUESS.
♪ HOW SWEET THE SOUND
>> Reporter: WHILE AMERICANS
CLUTCHED EACH OTHER AT
CANDLELIGHT VIGILS OVERNIGHT,
MANY CELEBRITIES TOOK TO SOCIAL
MEDIA TO EXPRESS THEIR
CONDOLENCES.
AMONG THEM MAYA ANGELOU, WHO
TWEETED, OUR COUNTRY IS
GRIEVING, EACH CHILD WHO HAS
BEEN SLAUGHTERED BELONGS TO EACH
OF US.
AND EACH SLAIN ADULT IS A MEMBER
OF OUR FAMILY.
IT IS IMPOSSIBLE TO EXPLAIN THE
HORROR TO OURSELVES AND TO OUR
SURVIVORS.
WE NEED TO HOLD EACH OTHER'S
HANDS AND TO LOOK INTO EACH
OTHER'S EYES AND SAY, I AM
SORRY.
IN THE WAKE OF THIS TRAGEDY, THE
AMERICAN CONVERSATION ALSO
TURNED TO GUN CONTROL.
>> HOW MANY MORE KIDS HAVE TO
DIE BEFORE YOU GUYS SAY WE WANT
LESS GUNS NOT MORE?
>> Reporter: ALSO SPEAKING OUT
IS ASTRONAUT MARK KELLY, WHOSE
OWN WIFE, FORMER CONGRESSWOMAN,
GABRIELLE GIFFORDS WAS
CRITICALCRITICA
CRITICALLY WOUNDED IN A MASS
SHOOTING TWO YEARS AGO.
HE POSTED ON FACEBOOK, QUOTE,
THE CHILDREN OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND ALL
VICTIMS OF GUN VIOLENCE, DESERVE
TO HAVE LEADERS WHO HAVE THE
COURAGE TO ENGAGE IN A
MEANINGFUL CONVERSATION ABOUT
GUN LAWS.
AS A COUNTRY, WE CAN'T WAIT.
>> THESE NEIGHBORHOODS ARE OUR
NEIGHBORHOODS.
AND THESE CHILDREN ARE OUR
CHILDREN.
>> Reporter: AND MICHAEL
BLOOMBERG, WHO HAS LONG BEEN
OUTSPOKEN ABOUT THE NEED FOR
STRICTER GUN CONTROL LAWS ALSO
ISSUED A STATEMENT.
SAYING, WITH ALL THE CARNAGE
FROM GUN VIOLENCE IN OUR
COUNTRY, IT'S ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE
TO BELIEVE THAT A MASS SHOOTING
IN A KINDERGARTEN CLASS CAN
HAPPEN.
IT'S COME TO THAT.
NOT EVEN KINDERGARTENS LEARNING
THEIR As, Bs AND Cs, ARE SAFE.
>> I'M SURE THIS DEBATE WILL
CONTINUE.
RIGHT NOW, OF COURSE, OBVIOUSLY,
THE FOCUS ON THE MORNING.
>>> IT IS TIME, NOW, FOR THE
WEATHER.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A QUICK
BREAK FROM OUR COVERAGE AND
CHECK IN WITH GINGER ZEE.
>> GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE.
WE START WITH A STORM IN THE
CENTER OF THE NATION.
THIS IS BRINGING RAIN AND A
RAIN/SNOW MIX TO PARTS OF
MINNESOTA AND NORTH DAKOTA.
NOW, AS IT MOVES EAST, IT WILL
CHANGE THE WEATHER IN THE
NORTHEAST, PRETTY SIGNIFICANTLY.
NICE FIRST OF THE WEEKEND, NOT
AS NICE SECOND HART OF THE
WEEKEND.
MORE THAN 60% OF OUR NATION IS
STILL IN DROUGHT.
WE HAVEN'T SEEN THE END OF THIS
BY ANY MEANS.
AND A LOT OF PEOPLE WILL BE
SEEING A LITTLE BIT OF RELIEF IN
THE WAY OF RAIN, EAST OF THE
MISSISSIPPI.
ALSO, THE PACIFIC NORTHWEST.
>> AND THAT IS YOUR NATION'S
WEATHER.
LET'S HEAD BACK OUT TO GEORGE.
>> OKAY, GINGER.
>>> WE HAVE MUCH MORE FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, COMING UP.
MORE DETAILS ON THE SHOOTER, THE
FAMILY OF THE SHOOTER AND HOW DO
WE TALK TO OUR OWN CHILDREN
ABOUT THIS TRAGEDY AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL?
[ Penélope ] I FOUND
THE BEST CAFE IN THE WORLD.
NESPRESSO.
WHERE I NEVER HAVE TO COMPROMISE
ON ANYTHING.
♪
WHERE JUST ONE TOUCH
CREATES THE PERFECT COFFEE.
WHERE EVERY CAPPUCCINO AND LATTE
IS ONLY MADE WITH FRESH MILK.
AND WHERE THE STAFF
IS EXCEPTIONALLY FRIENDLY.
♪
NESPRESSO. WHAT ELSE?
SO ALL OF YOU DO.
YES, FOR SURE.
NOW WHAT'S BETTER?
BEING ABLE TO SHOOT TWO LASERS
OUT OF BOTH OF YOUR EYES
AT THE SAME TIME
OR JUST ONE LASER
OUT OF ONE EYE?
[ all kids ] TWO!
[ Moderator ] OKAY, WHY?
IF IT'S JUST ONE BEAM -- OKAY,
IT DOES A LITTLE BIT OF DAMAGE.
TWO BEAMS -- IT WILL
MAKE SOMETHING EXPLODE!
AND THAT'S MORE FUN?
YEAH!
AND IT'S MORE POWERFUL
YOU'RE SAYING?
YEAH!
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S NOT COMPLICATED.
DOING TWO THINGS AT ONCE
IS BETTER.
AND ONLY AT&T'S NETWORK
LETS YOU TALK AND SURF
ON YOUR IPHONE 5.
♪
[ coughs ]
[ baby crying ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
ROBITUSSIN® LIQUID FORMULA
SOOTHES YOUR THROAT ON CONTACT
AND THE ACTIVE INGREDIENT
RELIEVES YOUR COUGH.
ROBITUSSIN®. DON'T SUFFER
THE COUGHEQUENCES™.
AND YES, I'M TALKING TO YOU.
MIKE HERE NEEDS
A "HONEY, I LOVE YOU EVEN MORE
THAN THE DAY WE GOT MARRIED"
NECKLACE.
WELL, MY TRULY UNIQUE SELECTION
IS LARGER
THAN ORDINARY JEWELRY STORES.
THERE.
THAT'S WHY HE WENT TO JARED.
But when I was in an accident...
IS LARGER
THAN ORDINARY JEWELRY STORES.
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
So I never missed a beat.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.
TO SAY GET WELL
TO YOUR LOVED ONES.
THIS CAME FOR YOU, MOMMY.
[ Female Announcer ] BUT WHEN
YOU SEND A KLEENEX® CARE PACK,
COMPLETE WITH AMERICA'S
SOFTEST TISSUE,
YOU'RE ALSO GIVING
A WARM GESTURE OF CARE.
KLEENEX®.
AMERICA'S SOFTEST TISSUE.
YOU'RE ALSO GIVING
A WARM GESTURE OF CARE.
she doesn't
Even though our really get us.
And she'll never know
who we are, or what...
No way,
Madden Girls??
Nike!
Who's your mommy now?
Famous brands. Famously easy.
Famous Footwear.
Victory is Yours.
I'VE GOT A NICE LONG LIFE AHEAD.
BIG PLANS.
SO WHEN I FOUND OUT
Medicare DOESN'T PAY
ALL MY MEDICAL EXPENSES,
I GOT A Medicare
SUPPLEMENT INSURANCE PLAN.
[ Male Announcer ] IF YOU'RE
ELIGIBLE FOR Medicare,
YOU MAY KNOW
IT ONLY COVERS ABOUT 80%
OF YOUR Part B
MEDICAL EXPENSES.
THE REST IS UP TO YOU.
CALL AND FIND OUT
ABOUT AN AARP Medicare
Supplement Insurance Plan,
INSURED BY UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company.
LIKE ALL STANDARDIZED Medicare
SUPPLEMENT PLANS,
IT COULD SAVE YOU THOUSANDS
IN OUT-OF-POCKET COSTS.
CALL NOW TO REQUEST
YOUR FREE DECISION GUIDE.
I'VE BEEN WITH MY DOCTOR
FOR 12 YEARS.
NOW I KNOW I'LL BE ABLE
TO STICK WITH HIM.
YOU'LL BE ABLE TO VISIT
ANY DOCTOR OR HOSPITAL
THAT ACCEPTS Medicare PATIENTS.
PLUS, THERE ARE NO NETWORKS,
AND YOU NEVER NEED A REFERRAL.
SEE WHY MILLIONS OF PEOPLE
HAVE ALREADY ENROLLED
IN THE ONLY Medicare Supplement
Insurance Plans
ENDORSED BY AARP.
DON'T WAIT. CALL NOW.
>>> IT SHOULD HAVE NEVER
HAPPENED TO OUR CHILDREN.
THEY WERE VERY LITTLE.
>> SUCH A SAD SATURDAY MORNING
HERE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
YOU SEE THE PAIN THERE.
YOU SEE THE GRIEF.
MOTHERS AND FATHERS MOURNING
THEIR CHILDREN THIS MORNING.
20 CHILDREN DEAD.
THE WORST SHOOTING EVER AT A
GRADE SCHOOL HERE IN THE UNITED
STATES.
THE GUNMAN, ADAM LANZA, WAS 20
YEARS OLD.
HE SHOT HIS MOTHER BEFORE COMING
TO THE SCHOOL TO SHOOT SO MANY
CHILDREN, ADULTS, AS WELL.
AS I SAID, THE DEADLIEST GRADE
SCHOOL SHOOTING EVER IN OUR
HISTORY.
AND, ELIZABETH, SO MANY PEOPLE
HERE HAVING SUCH A HARD TIME
COMING TO GRIPS WITH THIS PAIN.
>> IT'S UNIMAGINABLE, GEORGE.
I THINK EVERY PARENT WHEN THEY
HEARD THIS STORY BREAK, JUST WAS
IN SHOCK.
I FELT, I KNOW, PHYSICALLY SICK
TO MY STOMACH.
A LOT OF OTHER PEOPLE FELT THE
SAME WAY.
AND COMING UP IN THIS HALF HOUR,
WE'RE GOING TO WEIGH IN WITH
EXPERTS ON HOW TO TALK TO OUR
KIDS ABOUT THIS TRAGEDY, ABOUT
THE SHOOTINGS.
THEY WILL, OF COURSE, HEAR ABOUT
THAT.
IT VARIES WITH THE AGE.
IT VARIES WITH THE CHILD.
BUT THE EXPERTS HAVE GREAT
ADVICE.
IT'S ALL IMPORTANT THAT WE MAKE
OUR KIDS FEEL SAFE, EVEN AS THEY
LEARN ABOUT THIS HORRIFIC
MASSACRE, IN NEWTOWN, WHERE
YOU'RE STANDING, GEORGE.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
IT'S HARD TO FIGURE OUT HOW TO
GIVE THEM WHAT THEY NEED TO
KNOW.
I'M HERE WITH DAN HARRIS, WHO
HAS BEEN HERE FROM THE VERY
BEGINNING.
WE'RE GOING TO LEARN ALL OF THE
IDENTITIES OF THE VICTIMS THIS
MORNING.
>> WE'RE EXPECTING THAT THIS
MORPING IN A PRESS CONFERENCE
COMING UP.
HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW AT THIS
POINT.
WE'RE SEEING A MASSIVE
INVESTIGATION UNFOLD.
AT THE HEART OF THIS
INVESTIGATION RIGHT NOW IS THIS
QUESTION.
WHY?
WHAT WAS THE MOTIVE OF THE
SUSPECT, 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA?
HIS RAMPAGE BEGAN WITH THE
MURDER OF HIS MOTHER HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
HE THEN STORMED THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WHERE HE
KILLED 20 CHILDREN, MANY OF THEM
FIRST GRADERS AND SIX ADULTS.
POLICE SAY HIS MOM HAD SOME SORT
OF CONNECTION TO THE SCHOOL.
BUT IT'S UNCLEAR WHAT.
SHE MAY HAVE WORKED THERE AT
SOME POINT.
POLICE TELL US THEY'VE BEEN
INTERVIEWING PEOPLE WHO KNOW
LANZA.
WE KNOW HE USED AT LEAST THREE
WEAPONS.
THREE OF THEM SEMIAUTOMATIC.
ONE OF THEM A RIFLE.
OVERNIGHT, POLICE WENT AND
IDENTIFIED THE BODIES AND
NOTIFIED THE PARENTS.
THIS MORNING, THEY'LL BE
RELEASING PUBLICLY THE NAMES OF
THE DEAD AS THIS TOWN GRIEVES
AND THE ENTIRE COUNTRY GRIEVES
WITH THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN.
GEORGE?
>> THE FAMILIES, ONLY LEARNED
EARLY THIS MORNING, FOR SURE,
WHAT HAPPENED.
WE GO TO ABC'S JIM AVILA NOW.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING,
GEORGE.
WE'RE STANDING IN FRONT OF, NEXT
TO THE HOME, WHERE APPARENTLY
THIS KILLING SPREE BEGAN.
A TROUBLED SON, KILLING HIS
MOTHER.
A WOMAN THAT RELATIVES SAY, WAS
A MOM WHO WOULD HAVE DONE
ANYTHING TO HELP HER SON IF SHE
KNEW HE NEEDED HELP.
AS NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, IS
STILL TRYING TO MAKE SENSE OF
THIS INEXPLICABLE SHOOTING, NEW
DETAILS ARE EMERGING ON THE
LANZA FAMILY.
>> I REMEMBER THEM TO BE SHY,
QUIET, WELL-BEHAVED KIDS.
>> Reporter: 24-YEAR-OLD RYAN
LANZA, BROTHER OF ADAM, WAS
TAKEN INTO CUSTODY AND
QUESTIONED BY AUTHORITIES.
BUT POLICE SAY HE IS NOT
SUSPECTED OF BEING INVOLVED IN
THE SHOOTING.
RYAN WORKED AT ERNST & YOUNG IN
MANHATTAN.
INVESTIGATORS ARE LOOKING AT
WHETHER THE 20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER
WAS CARRYING RYAN'S I.D. AT THE
CAUSE OF THE SHOOTING, CAUSING
THE INITIAL MISIDENTIFICATION.
AUTHORITIES TOLD ABC NEWS, THEIR
MOTHER, NANCY LANZA, WAS FOUND
FATALLY SHOT AT THEIR
CONNECTICUT HOME.
>> SHE RAISED VERY NICE BOYS TO
ME.
THAT'S WHY I THINK IT'S A SHOCK
TO EVEN KNOW THEM AND REALIZE
WHO THEY ARE.
AND WHAT HE DID.
>> Reporter: STATE RECORDS
INDICATE SHE WAS DIVORCED FROM
HER HUSBAND IN 2009.
NANCY AND HER EX-HUSBAND, PETER
LANZA, WERE REQUIRED TO COMPLETE
A PARENTING EDUCATION PROGRAM,
NECESSARY FOR DIVORCED COUPLES
WITH CHILDREN UNDER 18.
>> THEY SAY THE FACT THAT THE
PARENTS WERE DIVORCED MUST HAVE
CONTRIBUTED TO IT.
>> Reporter: THE SHOOTER'S
FATHER, PETER LANZA, WAS A VICE
PRESIDENT AT G.E. CAPITAL, AND
HAD BEEN A PARTNER AT ERNST &
YOUNG.
HE IS REMARRIED AND WAS
QUESTIONED BY AUTHORITIES.
BUT IS NOT UNDER ANY SUSPICIOUS.
THE MOTHER WHO LIVED HERE ON
THIS STREET, WAS -- HAD SOME
CONNECTION TO THE SCHOOL, WE'RE
TOLD.
BUT THE SUPERINTENDENT SAID THIS
MORNING THAT SHE WAS NOT
OFFICIALLY EMPLOYED THERE.
SHE MAY HAVE VOLUNTEERED IN SOME
WAY.
AS FOR THE FATHER, THEY'RE
DIVORCED.
HE DOESN'T LIVE HERE.
HE LIVES IN STANFORD.
AND HE APPARENTLY FOUND OUT
ABOUT THE KILLING FROM A
REPORTER WHO WAS IN HIS DRIVEWAY
WHEN HE CAME HOME AND INFORMED
HIM.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>>> THE QUESTION GOES TO WHAT
WOULD MAKE A PERSON DO SOMETHING
LIKE THIS?
SOMETHING SO TERRIFIC TO
CHILDREN SO LITTLE.
LET'S BRING IN PSYCHIATRIST
DR. JANET TAYLOR TO TALK ABOUT
THE MIND OF THE SHOOTER.
CLEARLY, EVERYBODY UNDERSTANDS
THIS YOUNG MAN WAS MENTALLY ILL.
BUT TO PICK CHILDREN, YOUNG,
YOUNG CHILDREN, AS HIS VICTIMS.
I MEAN, THAT IS ABOUT THE WORST
THING YOU COULD DO.
WHAT DOES THAT TELL YOU ABOUT
HIS MOTIVATION?
ABOUT HIS STABILITY OR
INSTABILITY, OBVIOUSLY?
>> CERTAINLY, THERE IS AN EVIL
JUST HEINOUS QUALITY TO IT.
AND THE FACT IS, IT'S IMPOSSIBLE
TO PREDICT WHO WILL BE VIOLENT.
BUT RISK FACTORS ARE,
INDIVIDUALS WHO HAVE BEEN
EXPOSED TO PHYSICAL ABUSE,
SEXUAL ABUSE.
IF THERE'S AN UNDERLYING
PSYCHOLOGICAL IMPAIRMENT, WHICH
CERTAINLY HE WAS DESCRIBED AS
ODD AND IN THE AUTISM SPECTRUM.
IF THEY HAVE ACCESS TO GUNS AND
WEAPONS.
AND CERTAINLY, INDIVIDUALS WHO
MAY HAVE REVENGE IN THEIR MIND.
BUT WHO WANTS TO HURT INNOCENT
CHILDREN?
>> OBVIOUSLY, THERE'S A LOT OF
PEOPLE IN THIS COUNTRY THAT ARE
AUTISTIC OR HAVES ASPERGER'S
SYNDROME AND NEVER COMMIT A
VIOLENT ACT.
THIS YOUNG MAN, ACCORDING TO
POLICE, IS SHOOTING HIS MOTHER
AT HIS HOME, AND GETTING IN THE
CAR WITH HIS WEAPONS, DRIVING TO
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, WALKING IN
AND SHOOTING KINDERGARTNERS AND
FIRST GRADERS.
>> I THINK THE PREMEDITATIVE
QUALITY OF IT INDICATES A FACT
THAT YOU CAN BE MENTALLY ILL.
YOU CAN BE PSYCHOTIC AND KNOW
RIGHT FROM AMONG.
AND THIS CASE, I THINK HE
DELIBERATELY KNEW WHAT HE WAS
DOING.
CERTAINLY, HIS UNDERLYING MENTAL
ILLNESS, PRESUMABLY THAT HE HAD,
WAS NOT AN EXCUSE IN ANY WAY FOR
A WHAT HE DID.
>> THE FACT THAT THE TARGET WAS
YOUNG CHILDREN.
DOES THAT GIVE YOU ANY
INDICATION OF PERHAPS HE WAS
TRYING TO HURT SOMETHING THAT
MEANT SOMETHING TO HIS MOTHER?
>> I MEAN, PRESUMABLY THAT WOULD
BE THE LINK.
UNFORTUNATELY, WE WILL NOT KNOW.
BUT YOU HAVE TO THINK THAT THE
FACT HE KILLED HIS MOTHER AND
THEN WENT AND KILLED INNOCENT
CHILDREN, MAYBE THERE'S A LINK
BETWEEN HIS MOTHER AND THE KIDS.
OR MAYBE HE JUST FELT LIKE HE
WAS DOING SOMETHING SO HORRIFIC
THAT HE WOULD ALWAYS BE
REMEMBERED.
WE WON'T KNOW.
AT THE END OF THE DAY, WE HAVE
TO PRAY FOR THE FAMILIES AND
UNDERSTAND THAT AT SOME POINT,
WE WILL UNDERSTAND THE MOTIVE.
BUT IT STILL WILL NEVER BE
ENOUGH TO BRING THE POOR KIDS
AND ADULTS WHO DIED BACK.
>> THE FOCUS IS ON THE FAMILIES
AND THE VICTIMS.
>>> LET'S CHECK IN FOR THE
WEATHER AND GINGER ZEE THIS
MORNING.
>> THERE WERE THREE REPORTED
TORNADOES IN NORTH TEXAS AND
WIND DAMAGE, TOO.
THOSE STORMS ARE GOING TO
EVENTUALLY MOVE EAST.
BUT IT'S NOT GOING TO BE AS
STRONG TODAY.
IF YOU'RE IN THIS AREA FROM
MEMPHIS, TO JACKSON,
NEW ORLEANS, INCLUDED THERE, YOU
MAY HAVE GUSTY WINDS, SMALL
HAIL.
BUT IT'S NOT GOING TO BE AS
POWERFUL AS YESTERDAY.
REAL QUICKLY, CASCADE MOUNTAIN
SNOW.
8 TO 14 INCHES UP THERE IN PARTS
OF THE PACIFIC NORTHWEST WITH
THAT STORM.
>> THANK YOU, GINGER.
>>> WHEN WE COME BACK, HOW TO
TALK TO OUR CHILDREN ABOUT THIS
TRAGEDY.
IN 1919, MY ANCESTOR,
MARCEL TOLKOWSKY...
INVENTED THE IDEAL CUT DIAMOND,
UNLOCKING THE TRUE BEAUTY
OF THE DIAMOND.
FOR OVER 90 YEARS...
WE HAVE CONTINUED
TO PERFECT THIS DIAMOND.
[ Female Announcer ]
NOW KAY JEWELERS BRINGS YOU
TOLKOWSKY IDEAL CUT DIAMONDS --
FROM THE FAMILY THAT INVENTED
THE IDEAL CUT.
AT KAY, THE NUMBER-ONE
JEWELRY STORE IN AMERICA.
FROM OUR FAMILY...
TO THE BEGINNING OF YOURS.
YES! YES!
♪ EVERY KISS BEGINS WITH KAY
He is a good little monkey
and always very curious.
One day George got an important
letter...
He's built a rocket ship to
travel into space.
It's just the right size for a
clever monkey.
Do you want to go into space,
George?
You will have to be very brave.
Hi, Grandma!
Oh hi,. my little monkey!
Here.
Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
Everyone got on and they were
off to the launching site.
Google, how far is Earth to the
Moon?
Moon is 238,900 miles...
The great moment had come...
...5...4...3...2...1
[ Male Announcer ]
WATCH OUT, CASANOVA.
THERE'S A NEW LADIES' MAN
IN TOWN,
AND HE KNOWS TO SHOP AT
Walgreens DURING THE HOLIDAYS.
WE HAVE GREAT GIFTS
AT GREAT PRICES,
ONLINE AND IN THE STORE.
SO YOU'RE SURE TO FIND
SOMETHING
FOR THAT SPECIAL SOMEONE --
EVEN IF YOU HAVE
SEVERAL SPECIAL SOMEONES.
SHOP Walgreens FOR GREAT GIFTS,
LIKE Lindt Lindor Truffles,
AND GET UP TO 10,000
Balance Rewards POINTS
ON YOUR TOTAL PURCHASE, HERE.
At THE Corner
OF Happy AND Healthy.
ON OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network,
A CONNECTION YOU CAN COUNT ON.
INTRODUCING AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET
WITH MORE SPEED OPTIONS,
RELIABILITY
AND Wi-Fi HOT SPOTS THAN EVER.
GO TO OUR WEBSITE BELOW TO GET
U-verse HIGH SPEED INTERNET
FOR JUST 14.95 A MONTH
FOR 12 MONTHS WITH
A ONE-YEAR PRICE GUARANTEE.
IT'S ALL THE SPEED YOU NEED
ALL AT A GREAT PRICE.
OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network
GIVES YOU MORE
OF WHAT YOU ENJOY ONLINE.
AND WITH AT&T,
OUR WIRELESS GATEWAY
TURNS YOUR HOME
INTO A PRIVATE Wi-Fi HOT SPOT
THAT CONNECTS
YOUR Wi-Fi DEVICES
AND CAN EVEN SAVE ON YOUR
SMART PHONE DATA USAGE AT HOME.
GO TO OUR WEBSITE BELOW
TO GET AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET
FOR JUST 14.95 A MONTH
FOR 12 MONTHS WITH
A ONE-YEAR PRICE GUARANTEE.
THAT INCLUDES ACCESS ON-THE-GO
TO OUR ENTIRE NATIONAL
Wi-Fi HOT SPOT NETWORK,
WITH OVER 30,000 HOT SPOTS.
AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET.
NOW ON OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network,
A CONNECTION YOUR WHOLE HOUSE
CAN COUNT ON.
♪
>>> WE ARE BACK, NOW, FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE SEE THE PICTURES OF THE
GRIEVING PARENTS AND FAMILIES.
STRUCK BY THAT TRAGEDY AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AND ALL OF US PARENTS, LOOKING
FOR ADVICE ON HOW TO TALK TO OUR
CHILDREN ON SOMETHING THAT'S SO
HARD TO COMPREHEND.
I'M JOINED BY OUR CHIEF HEALTH
AND MEDICAL EDITOR, DR. RICHARD
BESSER FOR THAT.
FIRST OF ALL, THE KIDS SO
DIRECTLY IMPACTIVE, THE CHILDREN
IN THAT SCHOOL AND THIS
COMMUNITY.
>> THOSE CHILDREN ARE GOING TO
NEED SPECIAL CARE TO MAKE SURE
THIS EVENT DOESN'T DEFINE THEM
FOR THE REST OF THEIR LIVES.
UNLIKE OTHER YOUNG CHILDREN,
THEIR PARENTS ARE GOING TO NEED
TO TALK TO THEM CLEAR ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED HERE.
EXPRESS THEIR FEELINGS.
YOU WANT TO MAKE SURE THE
CHILDREN DON'T BECOME TRAGEDY
CELEBRITIES.
THAT THIS IS ALL THEY'RE KNOWN
FOR.
AS SOON AS YOU GET THEM IN
NORMAL ROUTINES, TO PICK THEM
SOMETHING FUN TO DO.
THAT'S IMPORTANT.
BUT PROFESSIONAL GRIEF
COUNSELORS ARE GOING TO BE A BIG
PART OF WHAT THESE CHILDREN
EXPERIENCED.
>> I HAVE A 7-YEAR-OLD AND A
10-YEAR-OLD.
MY 7-YEAR-OLD DIDN'T KNOW ABOUT
IT.
DIDN'T WANT TO KNOW ABOUT IT.
MY 10-YEAR-OLD HAD QUESTIONS.
HOW DO YOU TALK TO THEM?
>> IT'S GREAT IF YOU CAN SHIELD
YOUR 7-YEAR-OLD.
FOR 10-YEAR-OLDS, YOU WANT TO
LISTEN TO THEM.
THEY NEED TO SEE THAT YOU'RE SAD
BUT UNDER CONTROL.
IT'S OKAY TO BE ANGRY AND SAD.
BUT YOU'RE IN CONTROL OF THOSE
FEELS.
AND YOUR 10-YEAR-OLD IS GOING TO
WANT TO KNOW FROM YOU THAT
THEY'RE SAFE.
THAT THEIR WORLD IS GOING ON.
AND THE BAD PERSON HAS BEEN
CAUGHT AND LIFE GOES ON.
>> RICH, THANKS VERY MUCH.
>>> LET'S GO BACK TO ELIZABETH
WITH DR. JEN ASHTON.
>> THAT'S RIGHT, GEORGE.
I WAS WONDERING ABOUT THE FACT
THAT MY KIDS DON'T YET KNOW
ABOUT THIS.
A LOT OF KIDS DON'T.
WE'RE KEEPING THE TV OFF.
AT SOME POINT, THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST SAID DON'T BRING IT
UP IF THEY DON'T ASK ABOUT IT.
IS THATTING THE RIGHT THING TO
DO?
>> I THINK THE CHANCES OF THEM
NOT HEARING ABOUT IT IN SOME
FASHION ARE SLIM TO NONE.
I GOT A NOTICE FROM MY
CHILDREN'S SCHOOL, AS WELL,
ABOUT PLANS THEY WILL TAKE AT
THE SCHOOL ON MONDAY.
IT'S IMPORTANT FOR PARENTS TO
REMEMBER THAT HOW THEY DEAL WITH
THEIR CHILDREN, HAS TO BE BASED
ON AGE.
THE CONVERSATION YOU HAVE WITH A
5-YEAR-OLD IS VERY DIFFERENT
THAN A CONVERSATION YOU HAVE
WITH A 15-YEAR-OLD.
IT'S ALSO IMPORTANT TO REMEMBER
THAT THERE MAY BE A SPECTRUM OF
REACTIONS FROM CHILDREN WHO WERE
NOT AT THE SCENE.
IT MIGHT BE MILD.
IT MIGHT BE SEVERE.
AND IT MIGHT BE DELAYED.
IT MIGHT NOT APPEAR RIGHT AWAY.
>> IT'S IMPORTANT TO STAY CALM
WHEN YOU TALK WITH YOUR CHILD.
AND TO REASSURE THEM, THAT EVEN
THOUGH WE CAN'T TELL THEM YOU
WILL ABSOLUTELY BE SAFE AT
SCHOOL, SAY IT ANYWAY.
GUARANTEE THEM.
>> THAT'S KEY.
YOU WANT TO KEEP THE HONEST
COMMUNICATION OPEN.
YOU WANT TO ASK THEM QUESTIONS.
BUT YOU ALSO WANT TO LISTEN.
AND I THINK IT CAN'T BE
EMPHASIZED ENOUGH THAT THIS IS A
PERFECT EXAMPLE WHERE RECRUITING
THE ASSISTANCE OF TRAINED MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS IS VITALLY
IMPORTANT.
KIDS SOMETIMES CAN'T ASK FOR
HELP.
BUT ADULTS CAN.
>> DR. ASHTON, THANKS FOR YOUR
ADVICE.
>>> WE'RE BACK TO GEORGE IN JUST
A MOMENT. Capella University
rough economic times  ds
have led to an increase in
clinical depression.
Drug and alcohol abuse is up.
And those dealing with grief
don't have access to the
professional help they need.
When you see these issues, do
you want to walk away or
step up?
With a degree in the field of
Counseling or Psychology from
Capella University, you'll have
the knowledge to make
a difference in the lives of
others.
Let's get started at
CAPELLA.EDU
THE LATEST THING
TO WEAR WITH BEAUTIFUL TOPS.
BEAUTIFUL UNDERARMS.
WEAR WITH TOGA TOPS,
YOGA TOPS, AND VA-VA-VOOM TOPS.
Dove Go Sleeveless
MAKES UNDERARMS SOFT AND SMOOTH
IN JUST FIVE DAYS.
EFFECTIVE PROTECTION.
BEAUTIFUL RESULT.
ADVIL PM® OR TYLENOL PM.
THE ADVIL PM® GUY
IS SPENDING LESS TIME
LYING AWAKE
WITH ANNOYING ACHES AND PAINS
AND MORE TIME ASLEEP.
ADVIL PM®. THE DIFFERENCE
IS A BETTER NIGHT'S SLEEP.
WITH ANNOYING ACHES AND PAINS
AND MORE TIME ASLEEP.
HE IS A GOOD LITTLE MONKEY
AND ALWAYS VERY CURIOUS.
ONE DAY GEORGE GOT
AN IMPORTANT LETTER.
HE'S BUILT A ROCKET SHIP
TO TRAVEL INTO SPACE."
GOOGLE, HOW FAR IS EARTH
TO THE MOON?
THE MOON IS 238,900 MILES...
"THE GREAT MOMENT HAD COME."
3, 2, 1...
[ GIGGLING ]
LIVING WITH MODERATE TO
SEMEANS LIVING WITH PAIN.IS
IT COULD ALSO MEAN
LIVING WITH JOINT DAMAGE.
HELP RELIEVE THE PAIN
AND STOP THE DAMAGE
WITH HUMIRA, ADALIMUMAB.
FOR MANY ADULTS WITH
MODERATE TO SEVERE RA,
HUMIRA IS CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO HELP RELIEVE PAIN
AND STOP JOINT DAMAGE.
SO YOU CAN TREAT MORE
THAN JUST THE PAIN.
HUMIRA CAN LOWER YOUR
ABILITY TO FIGHT INFECTIONS,
INCLUDING TUBERCULOSIS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL EVENTS,
SUCH AS INFECTIONS, LYMPHOMA,
OR OTHER TYPES OF
CANCER, HAVE HAPPENED.
BLOOD, LIVER AND
NERVOUS SYSTEM PROBLEMS,
SERIOUS ALLERGIC REACTIONS,
AND NEW OR WORSENING HEART
FAILURE HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING HUMIRA, YOUR
DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU FOR TB.
ASK YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU LIVE
IN OR HAVE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL
INFECTIONS ARE COMMON.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU
HAVE HAD TB, HEPATITIS B,
ARE PRONE TO INFECTIONS
OR HAVE SYMPTOMS SUCH AS
FEVER, FATIGUE, COUGH, OR SORES.
YOU SHOULD NOT START HUMIRA IF
YOU HAVE ANY KIND OF INFECTION.
ASK YOUR RHEUMATOLOGIST ABOUT
HUMIRA, TO HELP RELIEVE PAIN
AND STOP FURTHER JOINT DAMAGE
BEFORE THEY STOP YOU.
[ Female Announcer ]
At Yoplait,
we want you to feel
even better
about your favorite flavors.
So when you call, tweet,
and post, we listen.
That's why Yoplait Light
and Yoplait Original
are now made with
no high fructose corn syrup.
And why we use
only natural colors
and natural flavors
in Yoplait Original.
So, anything else we can do
for you, let us know.
But you'll keep it
to yogurt, right?
'Cause we shouldn't really help
with your love life.
Yoplait. It is so good!
>>> YOU SEE THE GRIEF HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, TODAY.
AFTER 27 DEAD IN THE WORST
SHOOTING EVER AT AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
I'M GEORGE STEPHANOPOULOS,
JOINED HERE BY MY "GMA WEEKEND"
COLLEAGUE, DAN HARRIS.
AND, DAN, YOU DRIVE UP HERE.
IT'S THE DEFINITION OF RURAL
CONNECTICUT.
WE ASK THIS QUESTION.
HOW COULD IT HAPPEN IN A PLACE
LIKE THIS?
>> EVERY TIME WE RUSH IN TO
COVER THE AFTERMATH OF ONE OF
THESE MASS SHOOTINGS, WE HEAR
PEOPLE SAYING, HOW COULD IT
HAPPEN TO US?
AND EVER HAS THAT QUESTION RUNG
SO TRUE AS HERE.
NEWTOWN IS A CLASSIC, SMALL,
SLEEPY NEW ENGLAND HAMLET.
HOME TO FEWER THAN 30,000
PEOPLE, 60 MILES NORTH OF
NEW YORK CITY.
FOUNDED IN 1705, IT PLAYED A
ROLE IN THE REVOLUTIONARY WAR
AND THE UNDERGROUND RAILROAD.
THIS IS THE PLACE WHERE THE GAME
SCRABBLE WAS INVENTED, WHERE THE
TOWN'S SYMBOL IS A ROOSTER.
WHERE PEOPLE MOVE FOR SAFETY AND
SCHOOLS.
>> PEOPLE COME TO NEWTOWN FOR
THE SCHOOLS.
THE HUSBANDS WILL SACRIFICE THE
COMMUTE JUST TO COME TO NEWTOWN
BECAUSE IT'S A LITTLE BIT
FARTHER THAN ANYWHERE ELSE.
>> Reporter: THIS BEAUTIFUL,
BUCOLIC SPOT IS A STRANGE,
SURREAL BACKDROP FOR TACTICAL
TEAMS IN FULL BODY ARMOR, WITH
LONG GUNS DRAWN.
>> REALLY?
HERE IN NEWTOWN?
THIS SMALL TOWN.
YOU READ ABOUT THIS EVERYWHERE
ELSE BUT HERE.
AND IT'S HEART WRENCHING FOR THE
CHILDREN.
FOR THE PARENTS AND GRANDPARENTS
AND EVERYBODY.
>> Reporter: IT FEELS LIKE A
DREAM AND A BAD DREAM.
>> IT'S A NIGHTMARE.
>> Reporter: AS REALITY SINKS IN
HERE, THE FEELING OF ONE FOLOCA
DESCRIBES AS MAGICAL INSULATION,
HAS BEEN SHATTERED.
>> THEY KEEP SAYING ON THE TV,
NEWTOWN'S SUCH A NICE TOWN.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
NICE TOWN, NOT A NICE TOWN.
IT COULD HAPPEN ANYWHERE.
>> ON A PERSONAL NOTE, I USED TO
COME HERE AS A CHILD.
WE HAD FAMILY HERE.
AND I REMEMBER VIVIDLY PLAYING
IN THE QUIET CUL-DE-SACS WITH
THE OTHER LITTLE KIDS.
THIS REALLY BRINGS HOME QUITE
POWERFULLY THAT IT CAN HAPPEN
ANYWHERE.
>> AND A TOWN THIS SMALL, EVERY,
SINGLE PERSON TOUCHED.
>> INDEED.
>> WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
IRREGULAR HEARTBEAT.LAR GUY
THE USUAL, BOB?
NOT TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
BOB HAS AFIB:
ATRIAL FIBRILLATION NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
A CONDITION THAT PUTS HIM
AT GREATER RISK FOR A STROKE.
[ GPS ] TURN LEFT.
I DON'T THINK SO.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR YEARS, BOB TOOK WARFARIN,
AND MADE A MONTHLY TRIP TO THE
CLINIC TO GET HIS BLOOD TESTED.
BUT NOT ANYMORE.
BOB'S DOCTOR RECOMMENDED
A DIFFERENT OPTION:
ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
XARELTO® IS THE FIRST AND ONLY
ONCE-A-DAY PRESCRIPTION
BLOOD THINNER
FOR PATIENTS WITH AFIB
NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
THAT DOESN'T REQUIRE
ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING.
LIKE WARFARIN,
XARELTO® IS PROVEN EFFECTIVE
TO REDUCE THE RISK
OF AN AFIB-RELATED STROKE.
THERE IS LIMITED DATA
ON HOW THESE DRUGS COMPARE
WHEN WARFARIN IS WELL MANAGED.
NO ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING
MEANS BOB CAN SPEND HIS
EXTRA TIME HOWEVER HE LIKES.
NEW ZEALAND!
XARELTO®
IS JUST ONE PILL A DAY,
TAKEN WITH THE EVENING MEAL.
AND WITH
NO DIETARY RESTRICTIONS,
BOB CAN EAT THE HEALTHY FOODS
HE LIKES.
DO NOT STOP TAKING
XARELTO® RIVAROXABAN
WITHOUT TALKING TO THE DOCTOR
WHO PRESCRIBES IT FOR YOU.
STOPPING MAY INCREASE YOUR RISK
OF HAVING A STROKE.
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU DEVELOP ANY SIGNS
OR SYMPTOMS OF BLEEDING,
LIKE UNUSUAL BRUISING
OR TINGLING.
YOU MAY HAVE A HIGHER RISK
OF BLEEDING
IF YOU TAKE XARELTO®
WITH ASPIRIN PRODUCTS,
NSAIDS OR BLOOD THINNERS.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE TAKING XARELTO®
IF YOU CURRENTLY HAVE
ABNORMAL BLEEDING.
XARELTO® CAN CAUSE BLEEDING,
WHICH CAN BE SERIOUS,
AND RARELY MAY LEAD TO DEATH.
YOU ARE LIKELY TO BRUISE
MORE EASILY ON XARELTO®,
AND IT MAY TAKE LONGER
FOR BLEEDING TO STOP.
TELL YOUR DOCTORS
YOU ARE TAKING XARELTO®
BEFORE ANY PLANNED MEDICAL
OR DENTAL PROCEDURES.
BEFORE STARTING XARELTO®,
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ANY CONDITIONS,
SUCH AS KIDNEY, LIVER
OR BLEEDING PROBLEMS.
READY TO CHANGE YOUR ROUTINE?
ASK YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
FOR MORE INFORMATION
INCLUDING COST SUPPORT OPTIONS,
CALL 1-888-XARELTO
OR VISIT GOXARELTO.COM.
>>> WE WILL BE REPORTING FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, ALL DAY
LONG HERE ON ABC NEWS.
STAY WITH US.
>> EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY.
EACH PARENT, EACH SIBLING, EACH
MEMBER OF THE FAMILY HAS TO
UNDERSTAND THAT CONNECTICUT WE
ARE ALL IN THIS TOGETHER.
>> THE TIGHT KNIT CONNECTICUT
TOWN OF NEWTOWN IS MOURNING
TODAY AFTER ONE OF THE DEAD LIST
SCHOOL SHOOTINGS IN U.S.
HISTORY. LAST NIGHT MEMBERS OF
THE COMMUNITY