WAY YOU EAT.
IT WILL CHANGE THE WAY YOU LIVE.
IF YOU AND YOUR FAMILY WANT TO
LOOK AND FEEL YOUR BEST, THEN
YOU MUST CONTROL WHAT GOES INTO
YOUR BODY.
WE SIMPLY NEED TO RETURN TO
EATING MORE LIVE FOOD, MORE
FRESH FRUITS AND VEGETABLES,
WHOLE GRAINS AND NUTS-- REAL
FOOD, BURSTING WITH THE LIVE
NUTRIENTS OUR BODIES ARE
STARVING FOR.
BUT HOW DO WE FIND TIME TO DO
THAT?
IN JUST THE PAST THREE YEARS,
OVER FOUR MILLION PEOPLE HAVE
FOUND AN EASY ANSWER: THE
PROFESSIONAL QUALITY, FIVE-STAR
RATED PERFORMANCE AND HEALTHY
LIFESTYLE YOU GET WITH AMERICA'S
NUMBER ONE BLENDING SYSTEM--
NINJA!
GO ONLINE AND SEE WHAT BOTH
CONSUMERS AND EXPERTS ARE SAYING
ABOUT NINJA.
SEE HOW NINJA HAS IMPACTED THE
LIVES OF MILLIONS.
>> ONE OF MY FAVORITE THINGS
ABOUT THE NINJA IS HOW MANY
APPLIANCES IT HAS REPLACED
ON MY KITCHEN COUNTER.
>> IT WOULD CHOP IT ALL UP
IN SECONDS.
IT WAS SO FAST, IT'S SO
POWERFUL.
>> IT'S A FOOD PROCESSOR,
A DOUGH MAKER, IT EVEN MAKES
ICE CREAM IN SECONDS.
I TELL EVERYBODY ABOUT IT.
IT'S AMAZING.
>> Announcer: AND NOW, LIVING A
HEALTHY LIFESTYLE HAS BECOME
EVEN EASIER AND MORE POWERFUL.
ANNOUNCING THE WORLDWIDE LAUNCH
OF THE ALL-NEW NINJA MEGA
KITCHEN SYSTEM.
WITH 1500 WATTS AND TWO FULL
HORSEPOWER, IT'S NINJA'S MOST
POWERFUL, MOST VERSATILE,
HIGHEST PERFORMING KITCHEN
SYSTEM EVER.
WITH ONE SINGLE APPLIANCE YOU
AND YOUR FAMILY CAN NOW EASILY
ENJOY HEALTHIER MEALS, NUTRIENT
ENRICHED SMOOTHIES, JUICE DRINKS
AND GREAT-TASTING LOW-FAT
DESSERTS.
NINJA'S MASSIVE NEW POWER,
COMBINED WITH OUR BREAKTHROUGH
BLADE SYSTEM...
[WHIRRING]
ENABLES YOU TO CRUSH ICE TO SNOW
INSTANTLY, DELIVERING RESTAURANT
QUALITY FROZEN DRINKS.
IT TURNS WHOLE FRUITS AND
VEGETABLES INTO NUTRIENT
COMPLETE JUICE, LEAVING ALL THE
VITAMINS AND FIBER IN THE GLASS
SO YOU GET ALL THAT DELICIOUS
NUTRITION IN YOUR BODY.
WHETHER YOU NEED TO MAKE A
PITCHER FOR THE FAMILY IN OUR
EXTRA-LARGE 72-OUNCE JAR OR JUST
A SINGLE DRINK ON YOUR WAY OUT
THE DOOR WITH OUR ALL-NEW TWO
HORSEPOWER SINGLE-SERVE
TECHNOLOGY, NINJA GIVES YOU ALL
THE OPTIONS.
AND FORGET FAST FOOD!
WHAT YOU NEED IS NUTRITIOUS FOOD
FAST.
THE ALL-NEW EIGHT-CUP PROCESSING
BOWL BRINGS NINJA QUALITY FOOD
PROCESSING TO YOUR COUNTERTOP.
IT MAKES FRESH CHOPPED SALADS
AND DRESSINGS, SALSAS, SAUCES
AND LOW-FAT ICE CREAM...
IT EVEN GRINDS LEAN CHICKEN AND
BEEF AND MIXES AN AMAZING TWO
POUNDS OF DOUGH IN LESS THAN
20 SECONDS.
IT REPLACES UP TO $1500 IN
PROFESSIONAL JUICERS, BLENDERS,
FOOD PROCESSORS, MIXERS AND
SINGLE SERVE NUTRIENT BLENDERS.
IT'S THE ONE AND ONLY APPLIANCE
YOU NEED.
>> I HAD A FOOD PROCESSOR,
I HAD A JUICER, I HAD A SMOOTHIE
MAKER-- THEY'RE ALL GONE.
I'M USING THE NINJA FOR ALL OF
THOSE AND I ABSOLUTELY LOVE IT.
>> Announcer: NINJA HAS MADE
LIVING A HEALTHY LIFESTYLE
AFFORDABLE FOR EVERYONE.
SO STAY TUNED TO SEE HOW FAST,
FUN AND EASY MAKING GREAT
HEALTHY MEALS, DRINKS AND SNACKS
FOR YOU AND YOUR FAMILY CAN BE.
NOW, HERE'S YOUR HOST,
BRENDA PRICE.
[WHIRRING...]
>> WOW...
CAN YOU BELIEVE THAT POWER?
ICE, WHOLE VEGETABLES AND FRUITS
ALL IN A 72-OUNCE CONTAINER AND
IT JUST RIPS THROUGH IT LIKE
NOTHING.
HI, I'M BRENDA PRICE AND YOU'RE
ABOUT TO SEE, FOR THE FIRST
TIME, THE MOST POWERFUL AND
VERSATILE KITCHEN APPLIANCE YOU
COULD EVER DREAM OF.
AND HERE TO SHOW YOU JUST HOW
EASY, EXCITING AND DELICIOUS
EATING HEALTHY CAN BE, IS THE
MAN BEHIND THE NUMBER ONE
SELLING PROFESSIONAL BLENDER
SYSTEM IN AMERICA, MARK ROSEN.
>> HI, BRENDA.
>> HI, MARK.
>> I AM HERE TODAY TO INTRODUCE
YOU TO THE BRAND-NEW MEGA
KITCHEN SYSTEM.
NOW, WE STARTED WITH A TWO
HORSEPOWER MOTOR AND THEN WE
COMBINED IT WITH OUR NINJA BLADE
TECHNOLOGY TO DELIVER
PROFESSIONAL BLENDING AND
PROFESSIONAL FOOD PREP.
PROFESSIONAL BLENDING ALLOWS YOU
TO CRUSH ICE INTO SNOW FOR
INCREDIBLE, RESTAURANT QUALITY
FROZEN DRINKS AND SMOOTHIES.
WE SET UP A COMPARISON TO A
COMPETING TWO HORSEPOWER
PROFESSIONAL BLENDER THAT COSTS
NEARLY $500.
WE FILLED BOTH OF THE JARS WITH
SOLID ICE CUBES.
I WANT YOU TO SEE THE DIFFERENCE
THAT YOU GET WHEN YOU HAVE THE
NINJA BLADE SYSTEM COMBINED WITH
THE TWO HORSEPOWER.
ARE YOU READY?
>> I'M SO EXCITED,
LET'S DO THIS.
>> LET'S GO.
[WHIRRING...]
THE ICE IS TURNING INTO SNOW!
LOOK AT THAT!
TRY TAMPING THAT.
[WHIRRING FADES]
NOTHING DOES WHAT A NINJA
KITCHEN SYSTEM CAN DO.
CRUSHING ICE TO CREAMY SNOW LIKE
THIS IS SOMETHING THAT ONLY
HAPPENS WHEN YOU HAVE NINJA
BLADES.
IT'S SO INCREDIBLE WHEN YOU
COMBINE THAT WITH THE
PROFESSIONAL TWO HORSEPOWER.
CHECK THIS OUT, BRENDA.
OH, MY GOODNESS.
LOOK AT THIS-- THIS IS ALL
POWDERY, CREAMY SNOW.
LOOK AT THAT. >> WOW...
>> NOW, THE NINJA BLASTED THE
ICE INTO THE CREAMY SNOW, WHICH
IS THE SECRET INGREDIENT FOR OUR
RESTAURANT QUALITY FROZEN DRINKS
AND SMOOTHIES.
NOW, I'M GOING TO MAKE A
CLASSIC, RESTAURANT STYLE FROZEN
PEACH BELLINI.
I'VE GOT MY FROZEN, UNSWEETENED
PEACHES, AND NOW I CAN JUST POP
THEM IN THE JAR LIKE THAT...
AND ANY SPARKLING WINE OR CIDER,
LIKE I'M ADDING NOW...
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE READY TO GO.
[WHIRRING...]
LOOK AT THAT!
ALL THAT ICE IS CRUSHED INTO
SNOW IN SECONDS AND THAT'S WHAT
GIVES THAT REALLY PROFESSIONAL,
RESTAURANT STYLE SMOOTH, CREAMY
TEXTURE TO THIS BELLINI.
[WHIRRING FADES]
>> THIS IS ONE OF THOSE THINGS
I HAVE TO HAVE A TASTE OF.
>> YOU READY? >> YEAH.
>> LOOK AT THAT.
>> OOH!
MMM... ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS.
>> HOW'S THE TEXTURE?
>> IT'S FABULOUS.
IT'S A PERFECT SUMMER DRINK,
PERFECT ENTERTAINING DRINK.
>> SMOOTH, CREAMY SNOW--
THAT'S THE NINJA SECRET.
>> I'VE NEVER HAD A BLENDER
BEFORE THAT WILL CRUSH ICE TO
SNOW, THAT'LL TAKE WHOLE
VEGETABLES AND LIQUEFY THOSE AND
FROZEN FRUIT AND JUST MAKE 'EM
ALL SMOOTH.
I LOVE THAT.
I CAN DO THAT NOW WITH THE NINJA
AND I LOVE IT.
>> I CAN JUST THROW IN A HANDFUL
OF ICE, STRAWBERRIES-- INSTANT
SMOOTHIE, IN SECONDS.
>> THESE ARE BOTH TWO HORSEPOWER
PROFESSIONAL BLENDERS.
THIS ONE ACTUALLY COSTS ABOUT
$500, IT'S A VERY, VERY GOOD
BLENDER.
BUT WHAT I WANTED TO SHOW YOU IS
WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE WHEN YOU
COMBINE TWO HORSEPOWER
PROFESSIONAL POWER WITH OUR
INCREDIBLE NINJA BLADE SYSTEM.
SO WHAT I DID HERE IS I FILLED
UP BOTH JARS WITH SOLID FRUITS
AND VEGETABLES AND SOLID ICE
CUBES SO THAT THE DRINK, WHEN
IT'S FINISHED, IS GONNA BE NICE
AND COLD.
WE CALL THIS COMPLETE NUTRIENT
JUICING.
LET ME SHOW YOU THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN THESE TWO.
ARE YOU READY?
>> I'M SO READY. [CHUCKLES]
>> HERE WE GO.
>> ALL RIGHT, I'M GONNA
THAT ON... [WHIRRING...]
>> ALL RIGHT, YOU SEE THE WAY
IT'S PULLING IT ALL TOGETHER?
GOING, GOING, GONE!
ALL RIGHT, YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO
USE THAT TAMPER A LITTLE BIT
THERE.
[WHIRRING CONTINUES...]
ALL RIGHT, YOU SEE WHAT I'M
SEEING HERE, BRENDA?
>> YEAH.
>> LOOK...
[WHIRRING FADES]
LOOK AT THAT.
YOU SEE THE WAY I HAVE THAT
SMOOTH TEXTURE, NO TAMPING
REQUIRED, ALL BLENDED TOGETHER?
THAT'S WHAT MAKES INCREDIBLE
COMPLETE NUTRIENT JUICING.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO TRY HOW THAT
TASTES?
>> I WOULD, I CAN'T WAIT TO
TASTE IT, AND I CAN'T BELIEVE
HOW FAST IT HAPPENED.
>> AND REMEMBER, THAT WAS SOLID
FRUITS AND VEGETABLES, SOLID
ICE CUBES.
THIS IS A TERRIFIC DRINK.
IT TASTES GREAT, IT'S
SUPER-HEALTHY.
HERE YOU GO.
>> ALL RIGHT.
OH, MY GOSH.
>> ISN'T THAT WONDERFUL?
>> IT'S ABSOLUTELY DELICIOUS AND
IT TASTES GREAT.
>> AND IS IT COLD?
>> IT'S COLD AND EVERYTHING'S
BLENDED.
IT'S VERY SMOOTH.
I LOVE IT!
>> THAT IS COMPLETE NUTRIENT
JUICING AND IT'S DELICIOUS.
>> WITH THE NINJA I GET THE
FIBERS, I GET THE NUTRIENTS,
IT DOESN'T SUCK IT ALL OUT.
INSTEAD IT LIQUEFIES THE ENTIRE
FRUIT.
>> SO I DON'T HAVE TIME, AS WITH
THE VITAMIX, TO PLUNGE AND
SCRAPE AND PLUNGE.
AND WHAT I REALLY LIKED ABOUT
THE NINJA IS THAT THREE TIERED
BLADE, AND WHAT THAT DOES IS IT
PULLS EVERYTHING DOWN AND BRINGS
IT UP AND CONTINUES TO MIX SO
IT'S SUPER-QUICK.
>> Mark: BUT NOW, FOR THE FIRST
TIME, WE ARE INTRODUCING
PROFESSIONAL BLENDING IN A
SINGLE SERVE CUP.
YOU GET THE FULL TWO HORSEPOWER,
THE 1500 WATTS POWERING OUR
NINJA BLADES ONE SINGLE SERVING
AT A TIME.
THIS HAS NEVER BEEN DONE BEFORE.
THIS IS ABLE TO MAKE
COMPLETE NUTRIENT JUICING
IN A SINGLE CUP.
>> I LOVE THAT.
>> WHOLE FRUITS, WHOLE
VEGETABLES, SOLID ICE CUBES,
NO PROBLEM.
CHECK THIS OUT.
[WHIRRING...]
LOOK AT THAT! >> OH, MY GOSH!
>> IN SECONDS!
>> WOW!
>> LOOK AT THAT SMOOTH TEXTURE.
THAT'S 24,000 R.P.M. THERE.
LOOK AT THAT!
THERE IS NOTHING OUT THERE THAT
CAN DELIVER THAT KIND OF
PERFORMANCE.
YOU WANT TO TASTE THIS?
>> I REALLY WANT TO TASTE IT.
MMM!
OH, MY GOSH, THAT IS DELICIOUS.
AND IT'S THE SAME POWER,
THE SAME AMOUNT OF POWER THAT
WAS IN THE 72 OUNCES IN THIS.
>> EXACTLY THE SAME POWER
BECAUSE THE TWO HORSEPOWER IS
DRIVING THE BLADE SYSTEM FOR A
SINGLE SERVE OR THE LARGER
72-OUNCE CONTAINER.
THAT'S WHY THEY CAN BOTH DO
COMPLETE NUTRIENT JUICING.
>> A COUPLE OF MONTHS AGO MY
LITTLE BOY CAME HOME FROM SCHOOL
WITH A NOTE SAYING THAT HE WAS
IN THE OBESE RANGE, AND I CRIED.
I CAN HIDE THINGS IN HIS
SMOOTHIES THAT HE HAS NO IDEA
ARE THERE.
HE THINKS IT'S ICE CREAM,
BUT IT'S GOT TWO CUPS OF SPINACH
AND IT'S FULL OF NUTRIENTS AND
IT'S GREAT FOR HIS BODY, AND
THOSE ARE THE TREATS HE GETS NOW
AND HE'S THRILLED.
>> THE SINGLE SERVE ARE
ABSOLUTELY GREAT AND THEY GET
USED EVERY SINGLE DAY.
>> BRENDA, I KNOW THERE WAS SOME
URGENCY FOR YOU TO CHANGE TO A
MORE HEALTHY, FRESH DIET AS A
RESULT OF A SERIOUS ILLNESS.
WHAT WAS THE MOST CHALLENGING
PART OF MAKING THAT CHANGE?
>> WELL, MARK, AS YOU KNOW,
I SURVIVED BOTH BREAST CANCER
AND STAGE FOUR OVARIAN CANCER,
SO THE IMPORTANCE OF EATING
FRESH, NUTRITIONAL FOOD BECAME A
LIFE OR DEATH PRIORITY FOR ME.
I'D SAY THE BIGGEST CHALLENGE
WAS FINDING WAYS TO GET ALL
THOSE FRESH SUPERFOODS INTO MY
BODY.
JUICE EXTRACTION IS A GOOD IDEA,
BUT IT SEPARATES AND LEAVES OUT
A LOT OF THE NUTRIENTS AND FIBER
THAT I NEED.
>> COMPLETE NUTRIENT JUICING IN
THE NINJA SOLVES THAT PROBLEM.
IT MEANS TAKING WHOLE FRUITS AND
WHOLE VEGETABLES, INCLUDING ALL
OF THE NUTRIENTS AND FIBER, AND
CREATING A DELICIOUS, NATURALLY
SWEETENED DRINK.
THE NINJA BLADE IS SPINNING AT
AN INCREDIBLE 24,000 R.P.M.
WHICH IS 2-1/2 TIMES THE SPEED
AND POWER OF THIS COMPETING
PRODUCT.
BRENDA, YOU TRY THE NUTRIBULLET
AND I'M GONNA USE THE NINJA.
>> O.K., LET'S DO IT.
>> ARE YOU READY?
GET SET, GO!
[WHIRRING...]
LET ME SEE WHAT'S GOING ON
THERE...
[WHIRRING CONTINUES]
>> Brenda: WOW.
[WHIRRING FADES]
>> Mark: LOOK AT THAT SMOOTH,
CREAMY TEXTURE MADE FROM SOLID
FRUITS AND VEGETABLES MIXED
WITH ICE.
>> I'LL BE DRINKING MY DRINK
AND SUDDENLY THERE'S A BIG CHUNK
OF ICE IN THERE-- NOT WITH THE
NINJA...
BECAUSE I HAVE THE POWER.
I HAVE 1500 WATTS TO CHOP UP
ANYTHING I THROW INTO THERE.
>> YOU JUST STICK IT ON, PUSH
THE BUTTON AND GO AND IT'S DONE.
>> Announcer: THERE'S JUST NO
EASY WAY TO SAY IT.
THE MAJORITY OF US ARE
OVERWEIGHT OR OBESE FROM EATING
HIGH-FAT, LOW-FIBER PROCESSED
FOODS.
[♪...]
BUT NOW, LIVING A HEALTHY
LIFESTYLE HAS BECOME EVEN EASIER
AND MORE POWERFUL!
ANNOUNCING THE WORLDWIDE LAUNCH
OF THE ALL-NEW NINJA MEGA
KITCHEN SYSTEM.
WITH 1500 WATTS AND TWO FULL
HORSEPOWER, IT'S NINJA'S MOST
POWERFUL, MOST VERSATILE,
HIGHEST PERFORMING KITCHEN
SYSTEM EVER.
NINJA'S MASSIVE NEW POWER,
COMBINED WITH OUR BREAKTHROUGH
BLADE SYSTEM, ENABLES YOU TO
CRUSH ICE TO SNOW INSTANTLY,
DELIVERING RESTAURANT QUALITY
FROZEN DRINKS.
IT TURNS WHOLE FRUITS AND
VEGETABLES INTO NUTRIENT
COMPLETE JUICE, LEAVING ALL THE
VITAMINS AND FIBER IN THE GLASS
SO YOU GET ALL THAT DELICIOUS
NUTRITION IN YOUR BODY.
WHETHER YOU NEED TO MAKE A
PITCHER FOR THE FAMILY IN OUR
EXTRA-LARGE 72-OUNCE JAR OR JUST
A SINGLE DRINK ON YOUR WAY OUT
THE DOOR WITH OUR ALL-NEW TWO
HORSEPOWER SINGLE SERVE
TECHNOLOGY, NINJA GIVES YOU ALL
THE OPTIONS.
AND FORGET FAST FOOD!
WHAT YOU NEED IS NUTRITIOUS FOOD
FAST.
THE ALL-NEW EIGHT CUP PROCESSING
BOWL BRINGS NINJA QUALITY FOOD
PROCESSING TO YOUR COUNTERTOP.
IT MAKES FRESH CHOPPED SALADS
AND DRESSINGS, SALSAS, SAUCES
AND LOW-FAT ICE CREAM.
IT EVEN GRINDS LEAN CHICKEN AND
BEEF AND MIXES AN AMAZING TWO
POUNDS OF DOUGH IN LESS THAN
20 SECONDS.
>> THERE IS NO DOUBT ABOUT IT.
THIS IS THE MOST POWERFUL
BLENDER I HAVE EVER SEEN.
>> WITH, UM, THE NINJA, THE
BLADES ARE SO POWERFUL THAT IT
JUST PULLS IT ALL IN AND DOES
THE WORK FOR YOU.
>> THE NINJA WORKS AS A BLENDER,
A SMOOTHIE MAKER, A DOUGH MAKER,
A JUICER.
NOW I CAN GET ONE APPLIANCE OUT
AND DO EVERYTHING I NEED TO AND
HAVE LESS CLEANUP.
>> Announcer: THE NINJA MEGA
KITCHEN SYSTEM DOES WHAT $1500
IN PROFESSIONAL JUICERS,
BLENDERS, FOOD PROCESSORS,
STAND MIXERS AND SINGLE SERVE
BLENDERS DO, BUT YOU WON'T PAY
$1500, NOT $600, NOT 400, NOT
EVEN $300!
HERE'S WHAT YOU'LL GET: 1500
WATTS OF PROFESSIONAL POWER TO
INSTANTLY CRUSH ICE TO SNOW FOR
RESTAURANT STYLE DRINKS...
TWO FULL HORSEPOWER-- THAT'S
NEARLY TRIPLE THE POWER OF OTHER
BLENDERS...
EXCLUSIVE NINJA HIGH PERFORMANCE
BLADES, A GIANT 72-OUNCE
CONTAINER, EIGHT CUP
PROFESSIONAL FOOD PROCESSING
BOWL, AND PROFESSIONAL DOUGH
MIXING.
AND JUST WHEN YOU THOUGHT IT
COULDN'T GET ANY BETTER,
SURPRISE AND IMPRESS YOUR FAMILY
WITH THE WILDLY POPULAR,
AWARD-WINNING NINJA LOW-CALORIE
FRESH FRUIT ICE CREAMS, READY IN
SECONDS.
AND WHY IN THE WORLD WOULD YOU
BUY A SINGLE SERVE BLENDER WHEN
YOU CAN GET NINJA'S SINGLE SERVE
CUPS WITH NEARLY THREE TIMES
MORE POWER AND BLADE SPEED
INCLUDED WITH YOUR NINJA MEGA
KITCHEN SYSTEM.
PLUS, YOU'LL GET NINJA'S HEALTHY
LIVING GUIDE TO GET YOU STARTED
WITH OVER 30 RECIPES, MEAL PLAN
SUGGESTIONS AND TIPS FOR A
HEALTHY LIFESTYLE.
>> I KNOW YOU'RE GONNA LOVE MY
NEW NINJA MEGA KITCHEN SYSTEM,
SO I'LL LET YOU TRY IT FOR 60
DAYS, AND IF YOU'RE NOT HAPPY
FOR ANY REASON, JUST SEND IT
BACK, I'LL EVEN PAY THE RETURN
SHIPPING.
BUT IF YOU DO LOVE IT, AND I
KNOW YOU WILL, WHEN YOU ORDER
DIRECT FROM NINJA TODAY, I'M
GOING TO GIVE YOU MY FAMOUS
V.I.P. FIVE-YEAR SERVICE
GUARANTEE.
IF ANYTHING GOES WRONG WITH YOUR
NINJA MEGA KITCHEN SYSTEM IN THE
NEXT FIVE YEARS, WE'LL FIX IT OR
REPLACE IT FOR FREE.
WE'LL EVEN PAY THE SHIPPING
BOTH WAYS.
THERE'LL BE ABSOLUTELY NO COST
TO YOU, GUARANTEED.
NOW, THAT'S GOOD OLD-FASHIONED
CUSTOMER SERVICE.
>> Announcer: RIGHT NOW, THROUGH
THIS DIRECT FROM NINJA TV OFFER
ONLY, GET THE NINJA MEGA KITCHEN
SYSTEM FOR AN UNBELIEVABLE FIVE
EASY PAYMENTS OF ONLY $49.95.
BUT HOLD EVERYTHING!
IF YOU ORDER TODAY WE'LL
ACTUALLY CUT ONE OF THOSE
PAYMENTS TO JUST FOUR PAYMENTS
OF $49.95.
BUT THE VALUE JUST KEEPS COMING.
IF YOU ORDER TODAY YOU'LL ALSO
RECEIVE FREE SHIPPING!
AND DON'T FORGET TO ASK ABOUT
THE NINJA PROFESSIONAL PREP
SYSTEM.
TURN YOUR MEGA KITCHEN SYSTEM
INTO A COMPLETE FOOD PROCESSING
WONDER.
INSTANTLY SLICE AND SHRED
VEGETABLES, CHEESE, FRENCH FRIES
AND SO MUCH MORE.
SO DON'T WAIT-- CALL RIGHT NOW
FOR YOUR FREE SHIPPING, FREE
60-DAY TRIAL AND FREE FIVE-YEAR
V.I.P. SERVICE GUARANTEE.
THAT'S A TOTAL VALUE OF $340.
CHANGE YOUR DIET, CHANGE YOUR
LIFE, AND ALL FOR JUST FOUR EASY
PAYMENTS OF ONLY $49.95.
SO WHAT ARE YOU WAITING FOR?
CALL OR GO ONLINE RIGHT NOW.
[♪...]
>> Mark: THE MEGA KITCHEN SYSTEM
WITH TWO HORSEPOWER OFFERS
PROFESSIONAL POWER AND
PERFORMANCE IN FOOD PROCESSING
AND DOUGH MAKING.
WE'RE GOING TO MAKE HEALTHIER,
DELICIOUS CHEESEBURGERS THE
NINJA WAY.
NOW, BRENDA, WHAT I'D LIKE YOU
TO DO IS USE THE CUISINART OVER
HERE... >> O.K.
>> AND I'M GONNA USE THE NINJA.
AND NOW I'M GONNA ADD 2-1/2
POUNDS OF CHICKEN.
>> THAT'S A LOT OF CHICKEN.
>> O.K., HERE WE GO.
[WHIRRING...]
YOU SEE, IT'S ALL GETTING EVENLY
PROCESSED AND MIXED TOGETHER.
YOU SEE, OVER HERE, YOU'VE GOT
THE LARGER PIECES OF CHEESE ON
THE TOP STILL REMAINING;
IT'S NOT GETTING EVENLY MIXED
TOGETHER.
I HAVE SOME SUN-DRIED TOMATOES
AND RED BELL PEPPERS THAT HAVE A
NICE, SMOKY FLAVOR.
NOW GO AHEAD AND TURN THAT ON.
>> O.K.
[WHIRRING]
>> LEAVE IT ON FOR A LITTLE BIT.
[WHIRRING CONTINUES...]
SEE THE WAY THAT'S ALL MIXING
EVENLY TOGETHER...
>> OH, YEAH.
[WHIRRING STOPS]
>> YOU SEE, YOU STILL GOT THE
BIG CHUNKS OF CHEESE OVER THERE.
>> I GOT BIG CHUNKS OF CHICKEN
AND THE SUN-DRIED TOMATOES--
NONE OF THAT STUFF BLENDED.
MARK, THERE'S NO DOUBT THAT
NINJA IS A SERIOUS FOOD
PROCESSOR.
>> DELICIOUS NINJA
CHEESEBURGERS, ONES THAT YOUR
KIDS AND YOU ARE GONNA LOVE
EATING TOGETHER.
WHEN YOU HAVE A PROFESSIONAL
KITCHEN SYSTEM, MAKING FUN,
FRESH, EXCITING SALADS AND
DRESSINGS IS EASY AND FAST.
HERE WE GO-- BROCCOLI, HAM...
IN SECONDS, LOOK AT THE
CONSISTENCY, IT IS PERFECT.
ISN'T THAT EASY?
>> LOTS OF NICE COLORS.
>> MAKING SALADS IN MY HOUSE
SOMETIMES ISN'T SO EASY 'CAUSE
THE KIDS, THEY SAY, "DAD, I'M...
WE'RE NOT A BUNCH OF GOATS HERE.
I'M NOT JUST GONNA EAT SALAD FOR
DINNER."
BUT I AM GONNA SHOW YOU SOME
AMAZING CHOPPED SALAD RECIPES
THAT HAVE SOME GREAT PROTEIN,
SOME GREAT TASTE INSIDE.
>> AND SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
>> EXACTLY.
>> SOMETHING NEW AND DIFFERENT.
>> ALL RIGHT, LET'S MAKE THE
DRESSING FOR THIS. >> O.K.
>> I CALL THIS A CITRUS
SUN-DRENCHED DRESSING.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
ALL RIGHT, HERE WE GO.
[WHIRRING...]
IN SECONDS!
>> OH, MY GOSH.
THAT IS INCREDIBLE!
I LOVE IT!
>> ISN'T THAT TERRIFIC?
CITRUS SUN-DRENCHED DRESSING.
>> I WANT TO SMELL IT.
I JUST WANT TO SMELL IT WITH
THOSE FRESH ORANGES, THE CITRUS.
OH, MY GOSH...
>> ISN'T THAT TERRIFIC? >> YES!
>> NOW, IN YOUR HOME YOU CAN
PREPARE THE CHOPPED SALAD WITH A
TERRIFIC PRESENTATION LIKE YOU
SEE HERE.
>> IT SOUNDS DELICIOUS.
>> AND MY KIDS, THEY COME
RUNNING FOR SALAD NIGHT NOW
BECAUSE IT'S SO FUN AND
EXCITING.
LET ME SHOW YOU ANOTHER ONE WE
PUT TOGETHER... >> O.K.
>> THAT EVERYBODY LOVES AT
MY HOUSE.
YOU LIKE A LITTLE BIT OF HEAT IN
YOUR SALAD, MAYBE?
>> I DO. [CHUCKLES]
>> I CALL THIS-- GET READY--
GUACAMOLE ON FIRE SALAD
DRESSING.
>> OOH, IT'S MUY CALIENTE.
I LOVE THAT.
>> ALL RIGHT, SO I'VE GOT SOME
ONION, SOME LIME AND SOME
PEPPER.
>> THE JALAPENO.
>> THE JALAPENOS, THAT'S RIGHT.
WE'VE GOT SOME TOMATOES...
SOME CILANTRO...
SOME SALT AND PEPPER...
SOME AVOCADO, SOME VINEGAR,
A LITTLE BIT OF WATER.
WATCH, IT'S READY IN A SECOND.
[WHIRRING]
>> THAT IS AMAZING, AND LOOK HOW
BEAUTIFUL THE COLOR IS.
>> LOOK AT THE TEXTURE OF THIS.
>> YEAH.
>> ISN'T THAT TERRIFIC?
>> IT'S NOT CLUMPY.
IT'S NICE AND SMOOTH...
>> AND YOU HAVE TO TRY THIS.
>> AND A BEAUTIFUL COLOR.
>> WE'LL JUST MIX IT UP.
ARE YOU READY?
>> YES, I AM SO READY.
>> LOOK AT THAT.
>> PERFECT.
>> ALL RIGHT, TELL ME WHAT YOU
THINK OF THAT.
>> THIS IS A BEAUTIFUL SALAD.
I'LL TAKE A LITTLE BITE HERE.
[♪...]
MMM... [LAUGHS] IT'S FANTASTIC.
>> FUN FOR THE WHOLE FAMILY,
NUTRITIOUS.
>> IT'S DELICIOUS AND IT'S NOT
TOO HOT... IT'S DELICIOUS.
>> YOU CAN PUT IT ON TOP OF
CHICKEN LIKE THIS.
>> OH, THAT'S A GREAT IDEA.
>> AND YOU KNOW WHAT, I'M GONNA
TRY THIS ONE BECAUSE IT JUST
LOOKS SO AMAZING.
I LOVE THE CREAMY TEXTURE THE
AVOCADO IS GIVING...
MMM... YOU WANT TO TRY?
>> IT'S AS IF YOU CUT AVOCADOS
AND PUT IT ON IT; I LOVE THIS.
[♪...]
>> BRENDA, THIS IS A GREAT STAND
MIXER, BUT WE WANTED TO SHOW YOU
THAT THE NINJA CAN ALSO DO A
GREAT JOB WITH ALL TYPES OF
DOUGH AND ACTUALLY DO IT FASTER.
NOW, THE BREAD MIX INSIDE THE
STAND MIXER...
I'M JUST GONNA TURN THAT ON TO
SPEED TWO LIKE IT TELLS YOU
TO DO.
ALL RIGHT, WE'VE GOT THE
SPECIAL...
THE DOUGH SPEED OVER HERE,
SO I'M GONNA SET THAT UP LIKE
THAT... >> O.K.
>> I'VE GOT THE DOUGH SPEED
OVER HERE.
AGAIN, THE DOUGH SPEED
>> AND I'LL DO THE DOUGH SPEED
ON "CAKE MIX".
WOW, LOOK AT HOW FAST
EVERYTHING'S GETTING COMBINED.
>> NOW LOOK AT THAT!
CAN YOU BELIEVE THIS?
LOOK AT THIS!
THE DOUGH IS BASICALLY READY.
CAN YOU BELIEVE THAT?
>> THAT IS SO FAST.
>> I'M GONNA SHUT OFF THESE TWO.
LET'S SEE OVER HERE...
THAT'S NOT, THAT'S NOT
READY YET.
>> THAT'S NOT HAPPENING YET.
>> I THINK THE COOKIE DOUGH IS
READY HERE.
>> THIS IS DEFINITELY DONE.
AND WE'VE GOT OUR COOKIE DOUGH.
>> ALL RIGHT, NOW, THAT'S
STILL GOING.
LET ME SHOW YOU WHAT THIS
LOOKS LIKE.
LOOK AT THAT.
THE DOUGH IS READY IN LITERALLY
20 SECONDS.
ISN'T THAT INCREDIBLE?
>> IT'S GREAT.
>> O.K., NOW, OVER HERE YOU HAVE
THE PIZZA DOUGH, THAT'S IN A
PERFECT BALL, LOOK AT THIS.
AND OVER HERE, HOW GREAT DOES
THE HOUSE SMELL WHEN YOU'VE GOT
COOKIE DOUGH READY.
LOOK AT THAT.
ISN'T THAT GREAT?
WE JUST POP IN THE CHOCOLATE
CHIPS OR THE CARROTS AFTERWARDS.
>> WELL, AND I'VE GOT MY CAKE
MIX HERE, WHICH IS PRETTY EASY.
I CAN JUST POUR THIS IN
THE PAN...
[♪...]
OH, YEAH, JUST LIKE THAT.
COMPLETELY BLENDED.
>> WE MAKE PIZZA DOUGH, WE'VE
DONE COOKIES-- VERY QUICK.
I'VE USED THE KITCHENAID MIXER
FOR YEARS AND IT'S GREAT, BUT
IT'S SLOWER, IT TAKES A LOT
LONGER, SO I DON'T USE IT
VERY OFTEN.
>> Brenda: NOW, MARK,
I UNDERSTAND THAT YOUR
AWARD-WINNING, LOW-CALORIE
PEACH ICE CREAM RECIPE WAS THE
NUMBER ONE REQUESTED RECIPE
LAST YEAR.
>> THAT'S RIGHT, IT ABSOLUTELY
WAS, AND IT IS SO EASY TO MAKE,
I'M GOING TO SHOW YOU RIGHT NOW.
I'M GONNA ADD THE FROZEN
PEACHES...
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> I'VE GOT A LITTLE BIT OF
LOW-FAT MILK.
NOW THIS ONE I'M GONNA ADD SOME
FROZEN STRAWBERRIES.
NOW I'M GONNA SANDWICH THE
STRAWBERRIES AND IN BETWEEN I'M
GONNA PUT A LITTLE BIT OF GREEK
YOGURT, THIS IS REALLY HEALTHY.
AND THE SPECIAL SURPRISE, FULL
OF ANTI-OXIDANTS, I'VE GOT DARK
CHOCOLATE CHIPS HERE.
>> I LOVE DARK CHOCOLATE.
THIS IS PERFECT.
>> I'VE GOT MANGO... >> MMM!
>> THIS TIME I'M GONNA ADD SOY
MILK, AND I HAVE SOME PECANS.
>> OH, THAT'S A GREAT, GREAT
COMBINATION THERE.
>> ALL RIGHT, YOU DO THAT ONE,
I'M GONNA DO THESE TWO HERE.
READY, GO!
[WHIRRING...]
>> WE'VE GOT THE DUELING NINJAS,
I LOVE IT!
[WHIRRING FADES]
>> ALL RIGHT, LET'S SEE WHAT WE
GOT INSIDE. >> TA-DA!
>> LOOK AT THIS.
THIS IS, OF COURSE, THE
AWARD-WINNER FROM LAST YEAR,
LOOK AT THAT.
>> THE PEACH LOOKS BEAUTIFUL.
>> UNBELIEVABLE.
>> AND LOOK AT THE GREAT COLOR
THAT CAME OUT WITH THE MANGO.
I LOVE THIS.
AND THE CONSISTENCY IS AMAZING.
>> LOOK AT THIS STRAWBERRY WITH
THE CHOCOLATE CHIPS.
>> OH, YUM!
AND YOU KNOW WHAT, IT'S HEALTHY,
IT'S GOOD FOR YOU.
>> IT'S DARK CHOCOLATE CHIPS
WITH STRAWBERRY AND GREEK
YOGURT.
>> EXACTLY, NOW I'M GONNA TRY
THE MANGO AND PECAN.
WOW!
...O.K., THERE'S ONE FOR YOU.
I WOULD HAVE NO PROBLEM FEEDING
ANY OF THESE THINGS TO MY
FAMILY, TO MY KIDS.
>> I HAD A FOOD PROCESSOR,
I HAD A JUICER, I HAD A SMOOTHIE
MAKER-- THEY'RE ALL GONE.
I'M USING THE NINJA FOR ALL OF
THOSE AND I ABSOLUTELY LOVE IT.
>> Announcer: THERE'S JUST NO
EASY WAY TO SAY IT.
THE MAJORITY OF US ARE
OVERWEIGHT OR OBESE FROM EATING
HIGH-FAT, LOW-FIBER PROCESSED
FOODS.
[♪...]
BUT NOW, LIVING A HEALTHY
LIFESTYLE HAS BECOME EVEN EASIER
AND MORE POWERFUL!
ANNOUNCING THE WORLDWIDE LAUNCH
OF THE ALL-NEW NINJA MEGA
KITCHEN SYSTEM.
WITH 1500 WATTS AND TWO FULL
HORSEPOWER, IT'S NINJA'S MOST
POWERFUL, MOST VERSATILE,
HIGHEST PERFORMING KITCHEN
SYSTEM EVER.
NINJA'S MASSIVE NEW POWER,
COMBINED WITH OUR BREAKTHROUGH
BLADE SYSTEM, ENABLES YOU TO
CRUSH ICE TO SNOW INSTANTLY,
DELIVERING RESTAURANT QUALITY
FROZEN DRINKS.
IT TURNS WHOLE FRUITS AND
VEGETABLES INTO NUTRIENT
COMPLETE JUICE, LEAVING ALL THE
VITAMINS AND FIBER IN THE GLASS
SO YOU GET ALL THAT DELICIOUS
NUTRITION IN YOUR BODY.
WHETHER YOU NEED TO MAKE A
PITCHER FOR THE FAMILY IN OUR
EXTRA-LARGE 72-OUNCE JAR OR JUST
A SINGLE DRINK ON YOUR WAY OUT
THE DOOR WITH OUR ALL-NEW TWO
HORSEPOWER SINGLE SERVE
TECHNOLOGY, NINJA GIVES YOU ALL
THE OPTIONS.
AND FORGET FAST FOOD!
WHAT YOU NEED IS NUTRITIOUS FOOD
FAST.
THE ALL-NEW EIGHT CUP PROCESSING
BOWL BRINGS NINJA QUALITY FOOD
PROCESSING TO YOUR COUNTERTOP.
IT MAKES FRESH CHOPPED SALADS
AND DRESSINGS, SALSAS, SAUCES
AND LOW-FAT ICE CREAM.
IT EVEN GRINDS LEAN CHICKEN AND
BEEF AND MIXES AN AMAZING TWO
POUNDS OF DOUGH IN LESS THAN
20 SECONDS.
>> THERE IS NO DOUBT ABOUT IT.
THIS IS THE MOST POWERFUL
BLENDER I HAVE EVER SEEN.
IT'S A FOOD PROCESSOR, A DOUGH
MAKER-- IT EVEN MAKES ICE CREAM
IN SECONDS.
IT'S INCREDIBLE.
I TELL EVERYONE ABOUT IT.
>> THE NINJA WORKS AS A BLENDER,
A SMOOTHIE MAKER, A DOUGH MAKER,
A JUICER.
NOW I CAN GET ONE APPLIANCE OUT
AND DO EVERYTHING I NEED TO AND
HAVE LESS CLEANUP.
>> Announcer: THE NINJA MEGA
KITCHEN SYSTEM DOES WHAT $1500
IN PROFESSIONAL JUICERS,
BLENDERS, FOOD PROCESSORS,
STAND MIXERS AND SINGLE SERVE
BLENDERS DO, BUT YOU WON'T PAY
$1500, NOT $600, NOT 400, NOT
EVEN $300!
HERE'S WHAT YOU'LL GET: 1500
WATTS OF PROFESSIONAL POWER TO
INSTANTLY CRUSH ICE TO SNOW FOR
RESTAURANT STYLE DRINKS...
TWO FULL HORSEPOWER-- THAT'S
NEARLY TRIPLE THE POWER OF OTHER
BLENDERS...
EXCLUSIVE NINJA HIGH PERFORMANCE
BLADES, A GIANT 72-OUNCE
CONTAINER, EIGHT CUP
PROFESSIONAL FOOD PROCESSING
BOWL, AND PROFESSIONAL DOUGH
MIXING.
AND JUST WHEN YOU THOUGHT IT
COULDN'T GET ANY BETTER,
SURPRISE AND IMPRESS YOUR FAMILY
WITH THE WILDLY POPULAR,
AWARD-WINNING NINJA LOW-CALORIE
FRESH FRUIT ICE CREAMS, READY IN
SECONDS.
AND WHY IN THE WORLD WOULD YOU
BUY A SINGLE SERVE BLENDER WHEN
YOU CAN GET NINJA'S SINGLE SERVE
CUPS WITH NEARLY THREE TIMES
MORE POWER AND BLADE SPEED
INCLUDED WITH YOUR NINJA MEGA
KITCHEN SYSTEM.
PLUS, YOU'LL GET NINJA'S HEALTHY
LIVING GUIDE TO GET YOU STARTED
WITH OVER 30 RECIPES, MEAL PLAN
SUGGESTIONS AND TIPS FOR A
HEALTHY LIFESTYLE.
>> I KNOW YOU'RE GONNA LOVE MY
NEW NINJA MEGA KITCHEN SYSTEM,
SO I'LL LET YOU TRY IT FOR 60
DAYS, AND IF YOU'RE NOT HAPPY
FOR ANY REASON, JUST SEND IT
BACK, I'LL EVEN PAY THE RETURN
SHIPPING.
BUT IF YOU DO LOVE IT, AND I
KNOW YOU WILL, WHEN YOU ORDER
DIRECT FROM NINJA TODAY, I'M
GOING TO GIVE YOU MY FAMOUS
V.I.P. FIVE-YEAR SERVICE
GUARANTEE.
IF ANYTHING GOES WRONG WITH YOUR
NINJA MEGA KITCHEN SYSTEM IN THE
NEXT FIVE YEARS, WE'LL FIX IT OR
REPLACE IT FOR FREE.
WE'LL EVEN PAY THE SHIPPING
BOTH WAYS.
THERE'LL BE ABSOLUTELY NO COST
TO YOU, GUARANTEED.
NOW, THAT'S GOOD OLD-FASHIONED
CUSTOMER SERVICE.
>> Announcer: RIGHT NOW, THROUGH
THIS DIRECT FROM NINJA TV OFFER
ONLY, GET THE NINJA MEGA KITCHEN
SYSTEM FOR AN UNBELIEVABLE FIVE
EASY PAYMENTS OF ONLY $49.95.
BUT HOLD EVERYTHING!
IF YOU ORDER TODAY WE'LL
ACTUALLY CUT ONE OF THOSE
PAYMENTS TO JUST FOUR PAYMENTS
OF $49.95.
BUT THE VALUE JUST KEEPS COMING.
IF YOU ORDER TODAY YOU'LL ALSO
RECEIVE FREE SHIPPING!
AND DON'T FORGET TO ASK ABOUT
THE NINJA PROFESSIONAL PREP
SYSTEM.
TURN YOUR MEGA KITCHEN SYSTEM
INTO A COMPLETE FOOD PROCESSING
WONDER.
INSTANTLY SLICE AND SHRED
VEGETABLES, CHEESE, FRENCH FRIES
AND SO MUCH MORE.
SO DON'T WAIT-- CALL RIGHT NOW
FOR YOUR FREE SHIPPING, FREE
60-DAY TRIAL AND FREE FIVE-YEAR
V.I.P. SERVICE GUARANTEE.
THAT'S A TOTAL VALUE OF $340.
CHANGE YOUR DIET, CHANGE YOUR
LIFE, AND ALL FOR JUST FOUR EASY
PAYMENTS OF ONLY $49.95.
SO WHAT ARE YOU WAITING FOR?
CALL OR GO ONLINE RIGHT NOW.
[♪...]
THE PRECEDING WAS A PAID PROGRAM
FOR THE NINJA MEGA KITCHEN
SYSTEM, BROUGHT TO YOU BY
EURO-PRO.
[♪...]
h;x;x;x
Announcer: THE FOLLOWING IS
A PAID PRESENTATION BROUGHT TO
YOU BY MY PILLOW, INCORPORATED.
HELLO, I'M MIKE LINDELL.
I'VE INVENTED OF THE WORLD'S
MOST COMFORTABLE PILLOW.
I MAKE 'EM RIGHT HERE IN
THE UNITED STATES.
DO NOT CHANGE THAT CHANNEL
BECAUSE THE NEXT HALF-HOUR
IS GOING TO CHANGE YOUR LIFE.
[AUDIENCE APPLAUDS]
>> IT TOOK ME A WHILE JUST
TO GET OUT OF BED
AND REJUVENATE MYSELF AGAIN,
BUT AFTER HAVING THE MY PILLOW
I JUST FEEL SO MUCH BETTER...
JUST, EVERYTHING IS JUST WELL
TAKEN CARE OF, IT FEELS LIKE.
AND THERE'S NO PROBLEM ANYMORE.
I DON'T FIGHT WITH MY PILLOW.
>> I FALL ASLEEP WITH IT RIGHT
WHERE IT NEEDS TO BE