BEHAVE?
>> OF COURSE IR W
WEARING UNDER WEAR.
>> PEOPLE JUST NEED TO RELAX.
ANNOUNCER: AS KATIE TRIES TO GET
TO THE BOTTOM OF THEIR SUCCESS.
KATIE: WHAT'S THE SITUATION?
CAN YOU SHOW US?
I HAVE TO SEE IT FOR MYSELF.
ANNOUNCER: AND EXPLORES LIFE
BEYOND THE BOARD WALK.
KATIE: YOU MADE $11 LAST YEAR?
>> PLUS, SHORE OR NOT SO SHORE.
TEST YOUR "KATIE" KATIE COURIC
"JERSEY SHORE" TRIVIA.
>> I HAVE A SIGNATURE DRINK IN
THE HOUSE, WHAT IS IT?
KATIE: SNOOKI HAS A FAVORITE
FOOD, WHAT IS IT?
[CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
DISNEY-ABC DOMESTIC TELEVISION]
KATIE: HI EVERYONE, THANK YOU
FOR COMING.
SO, ANYBODY IN THE CROWD FROM
JERSEY?
THERE WE GO.
GARDEN STATE. 'RE ALL ABOUT THE
FROM JERSEY'S BIGGEST REALITY
STAR,ISING STAR, WHO'S
TACKLING SOME REAL LIFE
PROBLEMS.
WE'LL HEAR FROM HIM HOW HE JUST
SPENT $4 A DAY ON FOOD AND WHAT
THAT WAS LIKE.
SADLY FOR MANY FAMILIES THIS IS
THEIR REALITY.
BUT FIRST, SPEAKING OF REALITY
TV, THE SUN IS SETTING ON
"KATIE" KATIE COURIC "JERSEY
SHORE."
THE HIT REALITY SHOW IS COMING
TO AN END AFTER SIX SEASONS.
NO MATTER HOW YOU FEEL ABOUT THE
FIST BUMPING, ONE THING ISCLEARE
CLEAR, THE BOARD WALK WAS NEVER
BORING.
>> WHAT IS YOUR NAME SIR?
>> THE SITUATION.
>> STOP!
STOP!
>> GOT ARRESTED.
>> WHAT?
>> WHY AM I IN TROUBLE?
WHY AM I IN TROUBLE?
>> JOEY D.
♪
>> YOU ARE A [BEEP] SLUTTY
[BEEP]!
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KATIE: PLEASE WELCOME THE CAST
OF "KATIE" KATIE COURIC "JERSEY
SHORE," LADIES FIRST, SNOOKI,
JWOWW, SAMIE --
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
AND THE BOYS, VINNIE, MIKE THE
SITUATION AND RONNIE, COME ON
OUT, FELLOWS.
WHERE ARE YOU?
ARE THEY LATE AGAIN?
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
AND OF COURSE WE CANNOT FORGET
PAULY D. WHO'S JOINING US VIA
SATELLITE ALL THE WAY FROM
VEGAS.
HEY H ARE YOU?
GREAT TO HAVE YOU ALL HERE.
THANKS FOR COMING BY.
I GUESS IT'S THE END OF "KATIE"
KATIE COURIC "JERSEY SHORE."
WHAT DO YOU THINK ABOUT THIS?
>> IT'S DEFINITELY BITTER SWEET
BECAUSE IT BROUGHT US ON YOUR
SHOW TODAY, BUT WE'RE ALWAYS
GOING TO BE A FAMILY NO MATTER
WHAT.
KATIE: IS IT SAD?
ARE YOU GIRLS SAD ABOUT THE END
OF THIS?
>> VERY.
BECAUSE AT THE END OF THE DAY I
THINK IT CHANGED ALL OUR LIVES
FOR THE BETTER SO IT'S
DEFINITELY SAD.
KATIE: WHAT DO YOU GUYS THINK
THIS SHOW SUCH A SUCCESS?
I MEAN YOU WENT FROM SORT OF
REGULAR PEOPLE TO CELEBRITIES
OVERNIGHT LITERALLY.
WHY DO YOU THINK THAT'S THE
CASE?
>> I THINK IT HAD EVERYTHING
PEOPLE WANTED TO SEE.
EVERY EPISODE YOU SAW A FIGHT.
EVERY EPISODE YOU LAUGHED.
EVERY EPISODE YOU CRIED.
AND IT WAS ALSO LIKE THIS UNIQUE
GROUP OF PEOPLE FROM THE TRY
STATE AREA THAT I GUESS THE REST
OF THE COUNTRY DIDN'T KNOW
ABOUT.
KATIE: WERE YOU SURPRISED THAT
IT BECAME THIS HUGE HIT, WHERE I
THINK NINE MILLION PEOPLE WERE
WATCHING AN EPISODE, WHICH IS
REALLY, REALLY BIGBY TODAY'S
TELEVISION STANDARDS.
WERE YOU SURPRISED BY THAT?
>> DEFINITELY SURPRISED BECAUSE
THE FACT PEOPLE WERE TUNING IN
JUST TO SEE US.
WE WERE JUST BEING OURSELVES.
IT FELT GOOD.
I GUESS WE'RE ENTERTAINING.
[LAUGHTER]
KATIE: YEAH, YEAH.
AND WHAT ABOUT PAULY D., WERE
YOU SURPRISED?
>> I WAS VERY SURPRISED.
I JUST THOUGHT IT WAS GOING TO
BE COOL THAT WE WOULD FILM A
SHOW, PEOPLE WOULD WATCH IT.
AND I JUST WANTED TO TELL MY
FRIENDS I WAS ON TV, I WAS
EXCITED ABOUT THAT.
I DIDN'T KNOW EVERYBODY ELSE WAS
GOING TO WATCH TOO.
KATIE: I BET THERE WERE SOME
DOWNSIDES ABOUT BEING A SUDDEN
CELEBRITY.
WHAT WERE SOME OF THE REAL
CHALLENGES THAT YOU GUYS FACED
BECOMING SORT OF PUBLIC FIGURES
WHEN YOU WERE JUST SORT OF
REGULAR PEOPLE?
>> I THINK IT'S WE'RE SO USED TO
DOING OUR EVERY DAY ROUTINE,
WHICH WAS G.T.L.
WE COUNT GO TO THE SAME GYM, OR
THE MALL.
WE LOST A LOT OF OUR PRIVACY,
BUT GAINED A LOT.
WE WENT TO BEING SO NORMAL, TO
WALKING OUTSIDE AND EVERYBODY
WANTS A PICTURE AND A
PHOTOGRAPH.
>> EXACTLY.
IT SHOT US UP TO THAT LEVEL
WHERE EVERYBODY RECOGNIZED US,
BUT WE'RE STILL LIVING NORMAL
LIVES.
CAN'T AFFORD AN ENTOURAGE OF
SECURITY.
I STILL GOT TO GO TO THE CORNER
STAR JUST TO GET MY SANDWICH.
BUT I COULDN'T, YOU KNOW WHAT I
MEAN?
KATIE: RIGHT, RIGHT.
BUT HAVING SAID THAT, I THINK
WHILE YOU HAVE LEDGES OF FANS, I
THINK ALSO THERE HAVE BEEN A LOT
OF CRITICS OF THE SHOW WONDERING
WHAT THIS SAYS ABOUT US AS A
SOCIETY, OR AS A CULTURE THAT
PEOPLE ARE ACTUALLY REALLY
INTERESTED IN THIS SHOW.
AND IN FACT I PUT OUT SOME
QUESTIONS ON TWITTER, ACTUALLY
SOLICITTED QUESTIONS ON TWITTER
AND I WAS SURPRISED HOW VENOM US
PEOPLE WERE THAT YOU WERE GOING
TO BE ON THE SHOW.
>> PEOPLE JUST NEED TO RELAX.
I KNOW EVERYONE, WHEN THEY WERE
21 TO 26, THEY WOULD GO OUT,
THEY WOULD GO DO STUPID THINGS,
DRINK TOO MUCH, MAYBE GOT
ARRESTED FOR BEING TOO DRUNK.
THE ONLY THING IS WE'RE BEING
FOLLOWED BY CAMERAS AND EVERYONE
IS SEEING THAT.
SO NOBODY IN THIS ROOM CANNOT
TELL US THEY WENT CRAZY ONE
NIGHT.
>> I ALSO SAY WE'RE ACTUALLY
ABLE TO WATCH OURSELVES AND LOOK
BACK AT SOME OF THE MISTAKES
THAT WE HAVE MADE IN THE PAST
AND LEARN AND GROW FROM THOSE
MISTAKES AND ARE ABLE TO LOOK AT
OURSELVES AND BE LIKE OK, I
SHOULDN'T HAVE ACTED THIS WAY.
WE CAN KIND OF MOVE ON.
KATIE: WHAT ABOUT THE BACKLASH
FROM THE ITALIAN-AMERICAN
COMMUNITY INITIALLY WHEN THE
SHOW FIRST STARTED.
THERE WAS A LOT OF CRITICISM.
>> WE DEFINITELY REPRESENT
OURSELVES.
NOT EVEN EVERYONE IS ITALIAN ON
THE SHOW --
KATIE: RIGHT, YOU'RE SPANISH --
>> I'M SPANISH AND IRISH.
>> MY FAMILY IS BORN IN SICILY
AND THEY LOVE IT.
WE JUST REPRESENT OURSELVES.
>> YOU KNOW WHAT'S FUNNY?
WE WENT TO ITALY AND THE
ITALIANS WERE NICER TO US THAN
THE AMERICANS IN ITALY.
SO IT'S CRAZY.
KATIE: IS THERE ANYTHING
SPECIFIC THAT YOU GUYS REGRET
THAT SORT OF COME TO MIND?
>> THERE'S A LOT OF CRAZY STUFF
I REGRET.
>> WE LEARN FROM IT.
>> HONESTLY I CAN SAY PROBABLY
EVERY SINGLE ONE OF US GREW FROM
BEING ON THE SHOW.
YEAH, OF COURSE I REGRET NOT
WEARING UNDERWEAR.
REGRETS.  OF
[LAUGHTER]
BUT, I MEAN, NOW I KNOW TO WEAR
UNDERWEAR ALL THE TIME.
>> SEE, SHE LEARNED FROM IT?
KATIE: I'M HAPPY TO HEAR THAT.
LET'S TALK ABOUT HOW THINGS HAVE
CHANGED.
MIKE, YOU JUST GOT OUT OF REHAB,
SO YOU WENT THROUGH A TOUGH
PERIOD.
HOW ARE YOU DOING AND HOW WAS
THAT EXPERIENCE FOR YOU?
>> I WOULD HAVE TO SAY THAT
EXPERIENCE WAS PROBABLY THE MOST
DIFFICULT EXPERIENCE IN MY LIFE,
OR I THINK IN ONE'S LIFE.
>> I THINK IT WOULD BE VERY HARD
TO HAVE A CLEAN LIFE STYLE AND
TO BE IN THIS ENVIRONMENT, SORT
OF A MORE PARTY ENVIRONMENT,
RIGHT?
>> LIKE I SAID, IT WAS EXTREMELY
HARD, BUT I DIDN'T HAVE ONE
DRINK, ONE CIGARETTE.
I WAS ABLE TO RECOVER, GO
THROUGH REHAB, COMPLETE IT AND I
WOULD HAVE TO SAY ONCE APRIL
COMES UP IT WILL BE A YEAR.
KATIE: WELL GOOD,
CONGRATULATIONS.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
BY THE WAY, WHAT'S THE
SITUATION?
CAN YOU SHOW US?
I MEAN, THIS IS WHAT EVERYONE
TALKS ABOUT.
I GOT TO SEE IT FOR MYSELF.
>> WELL, THE SITUATION REFERS TO
MY ABS, AND I HAVE TO TELL THE
FANS, THE SEASON FINALE IS THIS
THURSDAY, ON MTV.
AT 10:00 --
>> SO YOU'RE NOT GOING TO LIFT
YOUR SHIRT UP?
>> THEY CAN WATCH ON TV.
KATIE: YOU'RE NOT GOING TO SHOW
US?
LOOK AT ALL THESE NICE PEOPLE.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
IS THERE SUCH A FUSS ABOUT YOUR
ABS, I WANT TO SEE THEM FOR
MYSELF.
>> MY MOM SAID NOT TO GIVE IT
AWAY FOR FREE.
KATIE: REALLY?
THAT'S GOOD ADVICE.
MEANWHILE SNOOKI, YOU HAVE A
BABY NOW.
HOW OLD IS YOUR SON NOW?
>> HE JUST TURNED 3 MONTHS.
KATIE: CONGRATULATIONS.
>> THANK YOU.
KATIE: WHAT IS MOTHER HOOD LIKE
FOR YOU?
>> IT'S AMAZING.
I KNEW IT WAS GOING TO BE
AWESOME.
BUT IT'S SO MUCH MORE AMAZING
THAN YOU EVER THINK IT WOULD BE.
KATIE: YEAH, YOU AND YOUR
BOYFRIEND ARE PLANNING TO GET
MARRIED?
>> WE'RE ENGAGED, WE'VE BEEN
ENGAGED SINCE FEBRUARY.
I THINK WE WANT TO GET A HOUSE
FIRST THEN GET MARRIED.
KATIE: THAT'S EXCITING.
WELL CONGRATULATIONS ON THE
BABY, THAT'S NICE.
>> THANKS.
KATIE: AND PAULY D., TELL ME
ABOUT WHAT YOU'VE BEEN UP TO.
AS FRANK SINATRA SAID, ANOTHER
FAMOUS BOY FROM NEW JERSEY.
IT WAS A VERY GOOD YEAR.
HOW MUCH MONEY DID YOU MAKE IN
2011?
[LAUGHTER]
>> I REALLY CAN'T COMPLAIN.
I'M DOING WHAT I LOVE TO DO, THE
SHOW FOR ME HAS BEEN A BLESSING.
I'M REALLY, I'M HAPPY A.F.C.
PART OF IT, HAPPY I MET
EVERYBODY ON THE SHOW.
I'M HAPPY TO HAVE LIFE LONG
FRIENDS AND I WAS HAPPY TO MAKE
SOME MONEY ALONG THE WAY.
>> AND IN FACT YOU MADE $11
MILLION LAST YEAR?
I'M SORRY, I KNOW THAT'S SORT OF
BAD TASTE TO MENTION MONEY, BUT
I MEAN, I THINK IT'S PRETTY
REMARKABLE.
A LOT OF PEOPLE OUT THERE ARE
THINKING MAYBE I SHOULD BE A
DEEJAY.
BUT YOU, I KNOW THERE'S TALK
THAT YOU MAY BE SPINNING AT
BRITNEY SPEARS UPCOMING WEDDING,
IS THAT TRUE?
>> THAT WOULD BE AWESOME.
NOTHING SET IN STONE, NOTHING'S
DONE.
I WOULD LOVE TO DO IT.
BRITNEY'S A FRIEND OF MINE.
I WOULD LOVE TO DO THAT.
KATIE: SO WHEN WE COME BACK,
WE'RE GOING TO TALK ABOUT HOW
THE CAST OF THE "KATIE" KATIE
COURIC "JERSEY SHORE" CAME TO
THE AID OF THE STATE OF NEW
JERSEY FOLLOWING HURRICANE
SANDY, AND WE'RE GOING TO TAKE
SOME QUESTIONS FROM THE AUDIENCE
AS WELL.
THAT'S RIGHT AFTER THIS.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
ANNOUNCER: UP NEXT, MORE WITH
THE CAST OF SHORE.
KATIE: HOW WERE YOU ABLE TO KIND
OF KEEP YOUR FEET ON THE GROUND?
>> I FELT COOL, BUT I FEEL
REALLY COOL NOW.
KATIE: YOUR 15 MINUTES OF FAME
ARE UP.
ARE YOU GUYS GOING TO BE OK WITH
THAT?
ANNOUNCER: THAT'S NEXT.
>> THIS REALLY SUCKS.
IT'S REALLY SAD.
KATIE: AND WE'RE BACK WITH THE
CAST OF "KATIE" KATIE COURIC
"JERSEY SHORE," THAT WAS SNOOKI
SEEING THE DAMAGE TO SEA SIDE
HEIGHTS FOR THE FIRST TIME AFTER
HURRICANE SANDY.
WHAT WAS IT LIKE FOR ALL OF YOU
TO WITNESS THE DEVASTATION AFTER
SANDY, TO SOME OF THE PLACES
THAT I KNOW YOU KNEW AND LOVED?
>> IT WAS JUST REALLY SAD
BECAUSE WE'VE BEEN HAVING
MEMORIES FOR LIKE, HOW MANY
SUMMERS NOW?
AND JUST TO SEE THE BOARD WALK,
IT'S NOT THERE ANY MORE, THE
RIDES THAT WE ALWAYS WENT ON IS
IN THE WATER.
IT'S DESTROYED.
IT'S SAD BECAUSE IT'S LIKE OUR
HOME.
KATIE: AND YOU GUYS DID A
SPECIAL TO RAISE MONEY.
WHAT WAS THE REACTION WHEN YOU
WENT OUT THERE?
>> I MEAN, USUALLY WHEN WE GO TO
SEA SIDE IT'S FUN, HAPPY.
WE LOOK FORWARD TO GOING TO
KARMA AND THE BOARD WALK AND THE
RIDES.
IT WAS SOMETHING WE NEVER
EXPECTED BECAUSE THE BOARD
WALK'S ALREADY LIFTED UP, IT'S
DEBRIS PILED UP WHEN YOU COME
OVER THE BRIDGE.
IT'S THE COMPLETE OPPOSITE.
KIDS LAUGHING, YOU SMELL THE
POPCORN AND NOW YOU'RE THERE AND
THERE'S SAND IN THE STREETS AND
IT WAS REALLY DEVASTATING.
KATIE: HOW MUCH MONEY WERE YOU
ALL ABLE TO RAISE?
>> AS OF A MILLION AND A HALF.
NOW.
>> IT'S STILL GOING.
KATIE: A WONDERFUL THING AND A
WONDERFUL WAY TO USE YOUR
CELEBRITY TO DO SOMETHING GREAT.
MEANWHILE, WE HAVE SOME
QUESTIONS FROM THE AUDIENCE.
LOT OF PEOPLE ARE BIG, BIG
"KATIE" KATIE COURIC "JERSEY
SHORE" FANS HERE.
THE FIRST QUESTION IS FROM
ALLISON.
>> HI, THIS IS FOR MIKE.
WHAT'S SOMETHING THAT YOU KNOW
NOW THAT YOU WISH YOU HAD KNOWN
BEFORE THE SHOW STARTED?
>> I WISH THAT SOMEBODY MAYBE
WOULD HAVE PREPARED ME FOR THE
ONSLAUGHT OF CRAZINESS.
KATIE: IT REALLY DOES MESS WITH
YOUR HEAD, DOESN'T I GUYS?
RIGHT?
>> THE THING IS WE'RE ALL STILL
HUMBLE, WE'RE ALL THE SAME
PEOPLE.
WE JUST FEEL COOL, I GUESS.
[LAUGHTER]
KATIE: DID YOU NOT FEEL COOL
BEFORE?
>> I FELT COOL BUT I FEEL REALLY
COOL NOW.
KATIE: FELT UBER COOL.
LIZ HAS A QUESTION FOR SNOOKI.
>> SNOOKI, I HAVE A 17-YEAR-OLD
SON AND I WAS JUST WONDERING, DO
YOU EVER WORRY WHAT THE EFFECT
OF YOUR SHOW HAS ON TEENAGE
KIDS?
>> I FEEL LIKE MAYBE IT HELPS
THEM, BECAUSE YOU KNOW WHEN THEY
GROW UP THEY'RE GOING TO
PROBABLY GO THROUGH THE SAME
THINGS.
IT'S NOT LIKE WE'RE TEACHING
THEM, YOU KNOW YOU SHOULD DO
THIS OR IT'S COOL.
IT'S MORE LIKE OH MY GOD MAYBE
I'LL GO THROUGH IT SOME DAY, AND
THIS IS HOW THEY DEALT WITH IT
IN THE FUTURE.
HOPEFULLY WE HELPED PEOPLE WITH
GOING THROUGH THINGS.
KATIE: I KNOW I READ IN THE "NEW
YORK TIMES" RECENTLY YOU
WOULDN'T LET YOUR SON SEE ANY
EPISODES UNTIL HE TURNED ABOUT
15 OR 16 YEARS OLD.
>> BECAUSE I WANT HIM TO GET IT.
I DON'T WANT HIM TO BE LIKE,
WHAT WAS THAT FOR?
I WANT HIM TO
BECAUS KNOW I DID THAT
BECAUSE I WAS FEELING THIS WAY,
I'VE LEARNED FROM IT.
SO I WANT HIM TO TAKE A LESSON
OUT OF WHAT I DID BECAUSE I KNOW
HE WILL GO THROUGH THE SAME
THINGS.
KATIE: HOW WILL YOU BE ABLE TO
ADJUST IF, QUITE HONESTLY, THIS
IS IT?
YOU DID "KATIE" KATIE COURIC
"JERSEY SHORE," YOU BECAME
HOUSEHOLD NAMES, BUT YOUR 15
MINUTES OF FAME MAY BE UP.
IF THAT WERE TO HAPPY, ARE YOU
GUYS GOING TO BE OK WITH THAT?
>> OH YEAH.
>> WE'RE NOT LIKE ALIENS WHERE
WE WERE RAISED ON A PLANET.
I WENT TO SCHOOL, I HAVE A
BACHELOR'S DEGREE.
RONNY SOLD MORTGAGES.
KATIE: TELL US ABOUT THAT SHOW
AND WHAT THAT HAS IN STORE?
>> SNOOKI ANCHED JWOWW AIRS
JANUARY 28.
>> ON TUESDAY NIGHTS.
>> SO YOU'RE GOING TO GET TO SEE
LORENZO'S BIRTH, JENNIE GETTING
ENGAGED AND JUST US BEING BEST
FRIENDS AND GROWING UP TOGETHER.
KATIE: MIKE, YOU WERE ASSISTANT
TO A MORTGAGE BROKER, AND A MALE
EXOTIC DANCER.
AND YOU GOT TAPPED FOR THIS.
SO, WHAT'S AHEAD FOR YOU?
>> YOU KNOW, EVER SINCE I WAS A
LITTLE BOY I DREAMED OF BEING ON
THE TV OR IN THE MAGAZINES.
NOW THAT I'VE DONE IT FOR A
NUMBER OF YEARS, AND HAVE BEEN
BLESSED TO SUCCEED, I WOULD LIKE
TO CONTINUE THAT.
KATIE: SNOOKI, YOU WERE IN
COMMUNITY COLLEGE TO STUDY TO BE
A VET TECHNICIAN.
>> I WOULD LOVE TO FINISH, I
HAVE ONE MORE SEMESTER.
KATIE: COULD YOU ENVISION
YOURSELF BEING A VET TECH?
>> OH, OF COURSE.
>> BEING IN RELATIVE OBSCURITY.
>> OBSCURITY?
[LAUGHTER]
KATIE: THAT'S LIKE WHEN PEOPLE
DON'T KNOW YOU.
>> OH, OK.
WELL, I WOULD STILL LIKE TO BE
KNOWN, BUT I WOULD LOVE TO BE A
VET TECH.
>> VINNY YOU'RE DOING THE TALK
SHOW FROM YOUR MOM'S HOUSE.
TELL US ABOUT THAT, BECAUSE
FIRST OF ALL, EVERYONE HERE
WANTS TO BE A TALK SHOW HOST.
SO I'M GETTING A LITTLE
CONCERNED ABOUT THE COMPETITION.
BUT, YOU WANT TO DO A SHOW IN
YOUR MOM'S HOUSE IN JERSEY AND
INVITE PEOPLE OVER FOR DINNER.
>> I'M FROM STATEN ISLAND SO MY
FAMILY HAS BECOME THEIR OWN
CHARACTER ON "JERSEY SHORE"
PEOPLE HAVE GOTTEN TO KNOW THEM.
I AM A TALK SHOW HOST, MY MOM
COOKS FOR THE CELEBRITIES, MY
UNCLE TELLS THEM BAD JOKES.
COMEDY ENSUES AND IT'S REALLY
RIDICULOUS BUT IT FORCES THE
CELEBRITY TO BE REALLY ORGANIC
AND REAL.
WE'VE GOT A COUPLE OF HUGE NAMES
ALREADY.
IT SHOULD BE FUN.
KATIE: THAT SHOULD BE FUN.
IS YOUR MOM A REALLY GOOD COOK?
>> AMAZING.
>> THE BEST COOK.
KATIE: I WOULD LIKE TO BE ON THE
SHOW THEN.
>> I CAME ON YOURS, YOU GOT TO
COME ON MINE NOW.
KATIE: SOUNDS GOOD, YOU'VE GOT
IT DOWN.
THAT'S HOW IT WORKS.
WHEN WE COME BACK, THE ULTIMATE
"JERSEY SHORE" TRIVIA CHALLENGE.
I'M JUST GOING TO OFFICIATE, BUT
THERE ARE PLENTY OF PEOPLE WHO
KNOW IT AND WE'LL GET TO THAT
RIGHT AFTER THIS.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
ANNOUNCER: UP NEXT, FANS GO HEAD
TO HEAD FOR A TRIVIA SHOWDOWN.
>> THERE WAS ANOTHER HAIR STYLE
THAT HELPED MAKE ME FAMOUS, WHAT
WAS IT CALLED?
KATIE: SNOOKI HAS A FAVORITE
FOOD, WHAT IS IT?
ANNOUNCER: THAT'S NEXT.
>> KNOW WAY ABOUT MY HAIR GEL.
CAN'T LEAVE WITHOUT MIGUEL.
WHEN I HIT "JERSEY SHORE," EVERY
GIRL LOVES THE NEW GUY.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KATIE: AND, WE'RE BACK WITH THE
CAST OF MTV'S "JERSEY SHORE."
NICOLE AND YEAH-YEAH ARE TWO OF
THEIR BIGGEST FANS.
WE'VE HEARD FROM THE CAST WHY
THEY THINK THE SHOW IS SO
POPULAR.
AND NICOLE, WHAT MAKES YOU LOVE
THIS GROUP SO MUCH?
>> I CAN RELATE TO THEM A LOT,
LIKE SNOOKI SAID BECAUSE I DON'T
DO THE SAME THINGS WITH ALL MY
FRIENDS, BUT WE WERE KIDS, WE DO
STUPID STUFF AND WE JUST HAVE
FUN AND THEY SHOW A GOOD TIME.
THEY'RE FUN TO WATCH.
THEY'RE ENTERTAINING.
>> WHAT ABOUT YOU YA-YA?
>> THEY'RE NOT AFRAID TO BE
THEMSELVES, THEY'RE GENUINE AND
THEY LIVE EVERY DAY LIKE IT'S
THEIR LAST AND HAVE FUN.
KATIE: OK, SO THAT QUALIFIES AS
A BIG FAN.
WE'RE GOING TO PLAY THIS GAME AS
WE MENTIONED.
CALLED "SHORE OR NOT SO SHORE."
ISN'T THAT CLEVER?
EACH CAST MEMBER GETS TO ASK A
QUESTION, WHICH EVER PICKS UP
THE DUCK PHONE, WHICH HAS A
PROMINENT ROLE IN THE SHOW, YOU
GET THE POINT.
SO HERE WE GO, PAULY.
GO AHEAD.
YOU HAVE THE FIRST QUESTION.
WHAT IS IT?
>> OK, SO BEFORE WE WENT OUT TO
THE CLUB, WHAT WAS THE FIRST
THING I WOULD YELL TO GET
EVERYBODY MOVING?
KATIE: OH, THEY'RE FIGHTING OVER
THE DUCK PHONE.
PICK IT UP, PICK IT UP.
>>
>> DID SHE GET IT?
>> T-SHIRT TIME?
IS IT THAT?
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KATIE: THESE GIRLS ARE GOING TO
COME TO BLOWS OVER THE DUCK
PHONE.
KATIE: OK DENA, WHAT'S YOUR
QUESTION?
>> A LOT OF US HAVE NICKNAMES ON
THE SHOW, WHAT'S MINE?
KATIE: WHAT WAS IT?
WHAT'S YOUR QUESTION?
>> I HAVE A SIGNATURE DRINK IN
THE HOUSE, WHAT IS IT?
>> RUM-RUM JUICE.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
COME ON!
COME I'M JUST GOING TO MAKE A
SUGGESTION, ARE YOU RIGHT-HANDED
NICOLE?
>> I JUST HAVE SLOW REFLEXES.
KATIE: ARE YOU RIGHT-HANDED?
>> YES.
KATIE: THEN YOU MIGHT HAVE A
BETTER CHANCE NOW.
SAMMY.
>> I'M ORIGINALLY FROM HASLETT
--
[LAUGHTER]
PUT IT DOWN!
>> THE BATTERY CAME OUT.
>> WHAT SPORT DID I PLAY IN
COLLEGE?
>> SOCCER.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KATIE: OK, MIKE, GO AHEAD.
>> OK, IF YOU'RE GOING TO HIT
THE CLUB, YOU HAVE TO G.T.L.
FIRST -- WHAT DOES G.T.L. STAND
FOR?
>> GYM, TAN AND LAUNDRY.
KATIE: OK, YAYA, I WOULD NOT
WANT TO MEET YOU IN A DARKENED
ALLEY.
[LAUGHTER]
YOU'RE AGGRESSIVE, GIRL.
GET IN THERE NICOLE.
>> I'M TRYING.
[LAUGHTER]
KATIE: OK, JENNY?
>> A LOT OF US HAVE TATTOOS.
NAME ONE OF MINE.
>> TIGER?
>> YEP.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KATIE: OK, VINNY?
>> ALL RIGHT.
[LAUGHTER]
SHE'S GOING TO GET THIS IN THE
FIRST THREE WORDS -- I HAVE A
FAMILY MEMBER WHO IS ALWAYS --
>> UNCLE GENO.
>> NOPE, NOPE, SHE'S WRONG!
I'LL FINISH.
I HAVE A FAMILY MEMBER WHO'S
ALWAYS THE LIFE OF THE PARTY,
WHO'S HIS NAME?
>> UNCLE GENO.
NINO.
KATIE: YOU CALL YOURSELF "JERSEY
SHORE" FANS?
>> I GOT IT, IT'S NINO.
KATIE: OK, YAYA GOT THAT.
AND FINALLY, SNOOKI?
>> MY HAIR IS RED NOW BUT THERE
WAS ANOTHER HAIR STYLE THAT
HELPED MAKE ME FAMOUS, WHAT WAS
IT CALLED?
>> THE POOF.
>> THEY BOTH SAID IT.
>> I GOT A WEAVE IN TODAY, CAN I
PLEASE HAVE THE POOF?
[LAUGHTER]
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KATIE: AND I HAVE TWO OTHER
QUESTIONS.
THEY'RE SUPPOSED TO BE
TIEBREAKERS, BUT AT THIS POINT I
DON'T KNOW WHO'S WINNING.
SNOOKI HAS A FAVORITE FOOD, WHAT
IS IT --
>> PICKLES!
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KATIE: NICE JOB.
OK, WHEN PAULY YELLS OUT -- WHAT
DOES IT STAND FOR?
[LAUGHTER]
I JUST WANT YOU TO KNOW, YOU ARE
SO IMPRESSIVE WITH YOUR "JERSEY
SHORE" KNOWLEDGE THAT YOU'RE
BOTH WINNERS TODAY.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
YOU BOTH GET TO GO HOME, I'M
SORRY, WE DON'T GIVE AWAY CARS
ON THIS SHOW.
NOT YET.
[LAUGHTER]
YOU BOTH --
>> A DATE WITH ALL OF THEM WOULD
BE FINE.
KATIE: YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO
DISCUSS THAT WITH THEM AFTER THE
SHOW, BECAUSE YOU GET "JERSEY
SHORE" CHRISTMAS TREES.
YOU GOT SNOOKI ORNAMENTS.
BY THE WAY, THE SEASON FINALE,
YOU'LL BE VERY HAPPY TO KNOW THE
SEASON FINALE OF "JERSEY SHORE"
AIRS DECEMBER 20 AT 10:00 P.M.
ON MTV AND THAT'S WHEN WE'LL BE
ABLE TO SEE THE SITUATION.
UP NEXT, WE'RE HEADING NORTH ON
THE JERSEY TURNPIKE, TALKING TO
THE MAYOR OF NEWARK, COREY
BOOKER, ABOUT A LOT OF THINGS
HE'S BEEN UP TO LATELY.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK AFTER THIS.
ANNOUNCER: UP NEXT, THE MAYOR OF
NEWARK, COREY BOOKER.
KATIE: THEY CALL YOU SUPER
MAYOR.
ANNOUNCER: HIS FOOD STAMP
CHALLENGE TO EAT ON JUST FOUR
DOLLARS A D
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KATIE: MY NEXT GUEST HAS BATTLED
DRUG DEALERS, DELIVERED DIAPERS
TO SNOWED IN RESIDENTS, EVEN
RUSHED INTO A BURNING BUILDING
TO SAVE A WOMAN TRAPPED INSIDE.
LAST WEEK HE MADE HEADLINES FOR
JUST SPENDING $4 A DAY TO EAT TO
SHINE A LIGHT ON THE STRUGGLES
OF PEOPLE LIVING ON FOOD STAMPS.
PLEASE WELCOME THE MAYOR OF
NEWARK, NEW JERSEY, COREY
BOOKER.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
FIRST OF ALL, I MEAN, WHO ARE
YOU?
SUPERMAN?
WHAT IS GOING ON HERE, COREY?
>> DEFINITELY NOT THE GREAT
THING ABOUT BEING IN NEWARK, YOU
SEE SO MANY SUPER PEOPLE.
I'VE SEEN SO MANY PEOPLE DOING
GREAT THINGS.
KATIE: MEANWHILE, YOU'RE A BIG
TWEETER, THEY CALL YOU SUPER
MAYOR AND PEOPLE HAVE BEEN
POSTING THINGS LIKE THIS.
CALL 911?
CALL CORY, SUPER MAYOR, AND
SOMEONE SUME IMPOSED YOUR HEAD
ON SUPERMAN'S BODY.
LET'S TALK ABOUT THIS WHOLE
CHALLENGE THAT YOU JUST EMBARKED
ON ABOUT FOOD STAMPS.
THAT WHOLE THING STARTED WITH A
TWEET, RIGHT?
>> WHEN I CAN'T SLEEP I'LL BE ON
TWITTER.
KATIE: I DO THAT TOO.
BECAUSE THAT'S THE ONLY THING
YOU CAN DO BECAUSE NO ONE'S
CALLING YOU, EMAILING YOU, I
GUESS I'LL CHECK OUT TWITTER.
>> MY STAFF TEASES ME.
BUT THE REALITY IS I GO BACK AND
FORTH TRY TO RESPOND TO PEOPLE.
BUT A YOUNG WOMAN SAID TO ME,
JUST THAT SHE DIDN'T THINK IT
WAS GOVERNMENT'S ROLE TO PROVIDE
NUTRITION.
AND I ACTUALLY DISAGREE WITH
THAT, BEING THAT I KNOW MANY
GREAT AMERICANS WHO AT DIFFERENT
TIMES IN THEIR LIVES, ESPECIALLY
THEIR CHILDHOOD HAD TO RELY ON
HELP AND SUPPORT.
SO I JUST SAID TO HER, THINKING
IT WAS A THROWAWAY COMMENT,
LET'S DO THIS FOOD STAMP
CHALLENGE.
I WOKE UP THE NEXT MORNING AND
IT HAD SPREAD AND I CALLED MY
STAFF.
WHO WASN'T EXPECTING THIS, AND I
SAID GUESS WHAT WE'RE GOING TO
BE DOING FOR THE NEXT WEEK.
KATIE: YOU DECIDED YOU WERE
GOING TO TAKE $30 FOR A WEEK,
WHICH WOULD COME TO ABOUT $4 A
DAY TO EAT FOR THE ENTIRE DAY,
AND FOR THE ENTIRE WEEK.
YOU WENT TO THE GROCERY STORE
WITH $30.
>> YES.
AND I DIDN'T KNOW IT WAS GOING
TO BREAK DOWN TO A $1.40 A MEAL.
THIS WAS A GOOD EXPERIENCE FOR
ME TO SEE EXACTLY WHAT THINGS I
SEE EVERY DAY BECAUSE ALL MY
STORES, I OFTEN SEE PEOPLE USING
FOOD STAMPS OR SNAP.
KATIE: I KNOW THAT YOU
BASICALLY, YOU RECORDED SORT OF
EVERY MEAL AND TALKED ABOUT WHAT
YOU WERE EATING, AND OBVIOUSLY
COMMUNICATED WITH YOUR TWITTER
FOLLOWERS, AND KEPT A VIDEO
DIARY EACH DAY.
SO LET'S TAKE A LOOK.
>> SO I'M HAPPY TO BE SITTING
HERE WITH A REALLY GOOD MEAL,
ACTUALLY TASTES REALLY GOOD, A
NICE SALAD WITH RICE AND BEANS.
BUT I CAN UNDERSTAND NOW,
CLEARLY ALREADY THAT I HAVE A
PUT A LOT OF FORETHOUGHT INTO MY
DAY'S OVER THIS WEEK ABOUT HOW
I'M GOING TO MANAGE MY MEALS.
KATIE: SO WAS IT HARDER, CORY,
THAN YOU THOUGHT IT WOULD BE TO
EAT ON THIS BUDGET?
>> A LOT HARDER.
IT BECAME EVERY DAY REALIZING
HOW MUCH I TAKE FOR GRANTED.
LOOK, I JUST GRAB AND GO AND
DON'T EVEN THINK ABOUT IT.
WHEN I REALIZE A CUP OF
STARBUCKS COFFEE WOULD BE AS
MUCH AS MY MEAL ALLOCATION, I
COULDN'T DO IT.
I HAD TO PUT A LOT OF
FORETHOUGHT, A LOT OF PLANNING.
AND JUST THINGS I DON'T DO
REGULARLY, WHICH IS COOKING SOME
MEALS, AND PREPARING FOOD.
SO IT WAS MUCH MORE CHALLENGING
THAN I EVEN THOUGHT.
KATIE: YOU GAVE UP COFFEE
BECAUSE IT WAS AN EXPENSE YOU
COULDN'T AFFORD.
THAT WAS TOUGH, HUH?
>> IT WAS PAINFUL.
QUITE LITERALLY, I GOT CAFFEINE
WITHDRAWALS, HEADACHES.
I WAS A BIT OF A GRUMPY GUY.
KATIE: I BET.
SHOW US, YOU BROUGHT SOME OF THE
THINGS YOU WOULD BUY.
I CAN'T IMAGINE YOU BOUGHT
LETTUCE IN A BAG, BECAUSE THAT'S
PRETTY EXPENSIVE.
>> FIRST OF ALL, AGAIN, HAVING
TWITTER, I GOT SO MUCH FEEDBACK
FROM PEOPLE CRITICIZING MY
SHOPPING CHOICES.
I WISH I HAD SPENT THE TWO,
THREE WEEKS LISTENING TO ADVICE
BECAUSE I MADE MISTAKES.
BUT THIS WAS ON SALE, SO IT WAS
A LOT CHEAPER THAN PEOPLE THINK.
THE SWEET POTATOS, MY GREATEST
DISCOVERY FROM THIS.
BECAUSE I USUALLY ONLY HAVE THEM
WHEN MY MOM PREPARES THEM ON
CHRISTMAS OR THANKSGIVING.
I JUST FELL IN LOVE WITH SWEET
POTATOS, BUT THEY WERE SO MUCH
CHEAPER, I THINK THEY WERE .69.
KATIE: VERY FILLING.
>> VERY FILLING.
THE FROZEN VEGETABLES WERE ON
SALE, CHEAPER THAN FRESH
VEGETABLES WHICH WAS INTERESTING
TO ME THIS WAS THE POWER, THE
CANNED FOOD, WHICH I GOT A LOT
OF CRITICISM FOR.
WHEN I JUST COMPARED THE PRICE
VERSUS FRESH FOOD OR BEANS, IT
WAS SO MUCH CHEAPER, THE UNIT
COST WAS SO MUCH CHEAPER.
KATIE: IN A CAN.
>> IN A CAN.
BUT INTERESTINGLY WHAT PEOPLE
WHO COOK WERE TELLING ME, WHEN
THEY SOAK THE BEANS, IT ABSORBS
A LOT OF WATER, AND YOU CAN TAKE
THAT INTO ACCOUNT.
KATIE: YOU COULD SPRETCH THE
BEANS MUCH FURTHER IF YOU BOUGHT
DRIED BEANS.
>> I GOT A LOT OF GREAT INSULTS
OVER TWITTER.
YOU MAY BE A RHODES SCHOLAR BUT
YOU KNOW NOTHING ABOUT COOKING.
KATIE: THAT'S THE BEAUTY OF
TWITTER, OR NOT.
>> I GOT SCHOOLED BY A LOT OF
FOLKS.
KATIE: WHAT OTHER ADVICE DID YOU
GET FROM PEOPLE IN SOCIAL MEDIA?
BECAUSE I IMAGINE A LOT OF
PEOPLE HAVE HAD TO LIVE THIS
WAY, OR YOU KNOW, HAVE A LOT OF
KNOWLEDGE OF THIS.
>> WELL, AGAIN, A LOT OF MOMENTS
TO MAKE LIGHT OF MY INABILITY TO
SHOP AND DO THINGS, BUT THE
REALITY IS THIS IS SOMETHING
PEOPLE DEAL WITH EVERY SINGLE
DAY.
THEY DON'T HAVE THE LUXURY OF
KNOWING IN ONE WEEK I'M DONE
WITH THIS.
MY MODEST BRUSH WITH WHAT 46
MILLION PLUS AMERICANS, BECAUSE
THERE ARE 46 MILLION AMERICANS
WHO SNUSE SNAP, BUT THERE ARE
MANY MORE AMERICANS WHO EVERY
DAY HAVE DIFFICULT CHOICES.
GO GROCERY SHOPPING OR PAY THE
MORTGAGE.
MAKE THE CAR PAYMENT OR BUY MY
CHILD A TOY.
SO WHAT WE'VE SEEN IN NEWARK IN
THE LAST FOUR YEARS, DURING THE
RECESSION, IS OUR FOOD PANTRIES
HAVE BEEN OVERWHELMED WITH
DEMAND.
AND THIS IS SOMETHING I'M HOPING
EVERYBODY UNDERSTANDS.
THIS IS NOT JUST ABOUT ONE
PROGRAM SNAP, IT'S REALLY ABOUT
FOOD JUSTICE, ENDING FOOD
INSECURITY IN THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA, WHICH WE HAVE THE
POWER TO DO.
AND SO WE CAN DO THINGS ON A
LOCAL LEVEL.
FARMERS MARKETS, FOOD STAMPS,
URBAN GARDENS, SUPPORTING OUR
FOOD PANTRIES, MAKING SURE THOSE
URBAN GARDENS AND FARMERS MARKET
ACCEPT FAMILY FIRST CARDS,
BECAUSE MANY DON'T.
KATIE: WHEN WE COME BACK WE'RE
ACTUALLY GOING TO TALK MORE
ABOUT THESE TWO KIND OF
CONFLICTING ISSUES THAT ARE
FACING AMERICANS, IRONICALLY,
HUNGER AND OBESITY, THAT'S RIGHT
AFTER THIS.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
ANNOUNCER: STILL TO COME,
SECRETS TO SAVE A LOAD OF CASH
ON GROCERIES.
KATIE: THIS IS REALLY $210 WORTH
OF FOOD THAT YOU GOT FOR $98.
ANNOUNCER: THAT'S LATER.
MAKING SPIRITS BRIGHT AND
BRINGING OUT THE STARS, ALL NEXT
WEEK ON "KATIE."
FIRST, HOPE AND HOLIDAY CHEER
FOR SURVIVORS OF HURRICANE
SANDY.
AND THE WEEK CONTINUES WITH --
KATIE: I LOVE MY JOB.
ANNOUNCER: HUGH JACKMAN AND
MORE, ALL WEEK LONG ON "KATIE."
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KATIE: WE'RE BACK WITH CORY
BOOKER, WHO IS THE MAYOR OF
NEWARK, NEW JERSEY WHO'S JUST
FINISHED HIS FOOD STAMP
CHALLENGE.
I NOTICED, CORY, IN YOUR DISPLAY
THAT YOU ONLY COULD AFFORD TWO
APPLES FOR THE ENTIRE WEEK.
>> RIGHT, FRESH FRUIT WAS SO
EXPENSIVE.
I HAD TO MAKE TOUGH DECISIONS
AND I LOVE APPLES AND I COULDN'T
AFFORD THAT MANY OF THEM.
KATIE: WHAT DO YOU THINK ABOUT
OBESITY IN AMERICA AND WHAT
PEOPLE AT THE LOWEST LEVEL OF
THE SOCIOECONOMIC LAD RER DOING,
OR HOW WE CAN HELP THEM BE
HEALTH YEAR AND MAKE BETTER FOOD
CHOICES AND MAKE BETTER FOOD
AVAILABLE?
>> FOOD INSECURITY, OBESITY, ALL
FROM THE SAME ORIGINS.
BUT YOU HAVE LOW INCOME
COMMUNITIES AND MANY PEOPLE WHO
ARE WORKING, THAT'S WHAT PEOPLE
DON'T UNDERSTAND.
MANY PEOPLE ON SNAP ARE WORKING
FULL-TIME JOBS.
KATIE: SOMETIMES TWO JOBS.
>> AND STILL NOT MAKING ENOUGH
MONEY.
THEY'RE OFTEN TRAPPED IN THE USE
OF EARLIER FOOD DESERTS, THEY
DON'T HAVE ACCESS TO FOOD.
WE'VE CREATED THE GRANT PROGRAM
TO GET THEM REFRIGERATED UNITS.
WE GOT THE FIRST IN THE CENTER
OF OUR CITY CALLED CENTRAL WARD,
OPENED UP THE FIRST NEW
SUPERMARKET IN 20 YEARS.
WE'RE DOING A LOT OF PRACTICAL
THINGS TO OPEN AND EXPAND
THROUGH FARMERS MARKET.
KATIE: IT IS TIME CONSUMING TO
BE ABLE TO EAT IN A HEALTHY WAY.
>> I FOUND MYSELF EATING THE
SAME THING OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
BEANS AND CORN, BEANS AND PEAS
AND I HAD A CRAVING FOR ICE
CREAM AND I GOT A TWEET BY
SOMEONE ANGRYLY, I SAW SOMEONE
BUYING FOOD ON STAMPS AND THEY
HAD X FOOD.
YOU WANT PEOPLE TO HAVE A
VARIETY OF FOODS.
WE HAVE TO WORK IN ALL OUR
COMMUNITIES TO MAKE SURE PEOPLE
HAVE ACCESS TO HEALTHY,
NUTRITION FOODS.
KATIE: OBVIOUSLY OBESITY IS A
HUGE ISSUE FOR CHILDREN AND
ADULTS, BUT SIMULTANEOUSLY WE
HAVE A BIG ISSUE WITH PEOPLE
BEING HUNGRY IN THIS COUNTRY
THAT I THINK MANY PEOPLE DON'T
REALLY APPRECIATE OR UNDERSTAND.
>> I LOVE THE TERM FOOD
INSECURITY AND NOT KNOWING WHERE
YOUR NEXT MEAL COMES FROM,
HAVING THIS PAIN OF
UNDERSTANDING THAT YOU'RE BARELY
GOING TO MAKE YOUR RENT PAYMENT
IF YOU DO, YOU'RE NOT GOING TO
BE ABLE TO AFFORD FOOD.
THE PAIN YOU FEEL WALKING
THROUGH A SHOPPING CENTER WITH A
CHILD, TWO POINTS TO FOOD THEY
WANT AND YOU KNOW THERE'S NO WAY
YOU'RE GOING TO BE ABLE TO
AFFORD TO GIVE THEM WHAT YOU
WANT.
KATIE: HOW DO YOU TACKLE ISSUES
SIMULTANEOUSLY, IT'S TRICKY
ISN'T IT?
>> IT IS TRICKY.
SEVEN YEARS NOW I'VE BEEN THE
MAYOR OF NEWARK.
GOING THROUGH THIS WONDERFUL
TRANSFORMATION.
MY METAPHOR USED TO BE I WAS A
PRISONER OF HOPE.
NOW MY METAPHOR OF LIFE IS I'M
HOPE UNHINGED BECAUSE I KNOW
WHEN MY COMMUNITY, IN NEW
JERSEY, WHEN AMERICA FOCUSES ON
ISSUES, REALLY FOCUSES ON THEM.
WE CAN SOLVE PROBLEMS.
SO I'M ONE OF THESE PEOPLE THAT
STILL BELIEVE YOU CAN BANISH
THIS IF WE ALL TOOK
RESPONSIBILITY FROM IT.
MOST OF US, IF WE LOOK INTO OUR
AN AN ZESTRY, THERE WERE PEOPLE
THAT WERE POOR, BENEFITTED FROM
THE LOVE, COMPASSION OF OTHERS.
THAT'S OUR RESPONSIBILITY, THE
ONLY WAY WE CAN PAY BACK WHAT
WILL HAPPEN FOR MY GRANDMOTHER,
WHAT HAPPENED FOR MY FATHER WHO
WAS BORN TO A POOR, SINNLE
MOTHER.
WE JUST NEEDED ACTIVISM THAT
STEMS FROM A CONSCIOUSNESS THAT
THERE ARE PEOPLE IN THIS COUNTRY
WHO ARE STRUGGLING IN SILENCE,
WHO ARE STRUGGLING WITHOUT THE
LIGHT AND ATTENTION THAT IT
REALLY DESERVES.
IF WE GAVE IT, WE COULD DISPEL
THE DARKNESS THAT AFFECTS TOO
MANY OF US.
KATIE: WHAT ABOUT EXPANDING YOUR
ROLE?
I KNOW THERE'S BEEN A LOT OF
SPECULATION THAT YOU MADE RUN
FOR GOVERNOR OF NG AND YOU'RE
MAKING A DECISION ABOUT THAT IN
THE NEXT FEW DAYS.
>> YEAH, IN THE NEXT WEEK OR SO,
TWO WEEKS, I'M GOING TO TAKE
SOME TIME TO FIGURE OUT WHAT'S
NEXT IN MY CAREER.
I'VE BEEN MAYOR NOW, IN MY
SECOND TERM AND I'LL THINK HARD
ABOUT RUNNING FOR THE UNITED
STATES SENATE.
WE HAVE A GREAT SENATOR THERE,
BUT HE MAY BE RETIRING, SO I'M
GOING TO THINK HARD ABOUT THE
SENATE SEAT AND COME OUT WITH A
DECISION SOON.
BY THE WAY, AFTER I MAKE THAT
DECISION, I THEN HAVE TO TURN TO
THE VOTERS AND THEY HAVE TO
DECIDE AM I WORTHY OF THEIR VOTE
AND SUPPORT?
KATIE: YOU CAN SEE WHY KELLY IS
SUCH AN EFFECTIVE POLITICIAN,
LIKE SIGN ME UP.
I KNOW YOU DIDN'T USE COUPONS
WHEN YOU DID YOUR FOOD STAMP
CHALLENGE.
BUT WHEN WE COME BACK, I KNOW
YOU WISH YOU HAD.
SO WE'VE GOT SOMEONE WHO CALLS
HERSELF THE COUPON MOM WHO WILL
SHOW US HOW TO GET MORE BANG FOR
YOUR BUCK.
I THINK IT WILL BE HELPFUL FOR
ANYBODY WHO'S SHOPPING ON A
BUDGET.
SO THAT'S RIGHT AFTER THIS.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KATIE: OK, NOW THE QUESTION IS
CAN WE REALLY EAT HEALTHY AND
SAVE SOME MONEY?
NEWARK MAYOR CORY BOOKER COULD
HAVE USED A LESSON FROM
STEPHANIE.
SHE MANAGES THE POPULAR WEBSITE
THE COUPON MOM.
>> I'M STEPHANIE NELSON AND THEY
CALL ME THE COUPON MOM.
I LOVE TO TEACH PEOPLE HOW TO
SAVE MONEY ON GROCERIES, AND
TODAY WE'RE GOING TO BE BUYING
GROCERIES FOR A FAMILY OF FOUR
FOR A FULL WEEK ON A BUDGET OF
$120.
COME WITH ME.
NOW TO SAVE A LOT OF MONEY YOU
NEED THE RIGHT TOOLS.
EVERY SHOPPER NEEDS A LIST, WE
STICK TO THE LIST.
AND YOU NEED THE STORE CIRCULAR.
THIS IS YOUR ROAD MAP TO
SAVINGS.
OF COURSE YOU NEED LOTS OF
COUPONS AND DON'T FORGET A
CALCULATOR TO MAKE SURE YOU STAY
ON BUDGET.
LET'S GO.
THE EASIEST WAY TO SAVE MONEY ON
FRESH PRODUCE IS TO DO IT
YOURSELF.
WASH YOUR OWN LETTUCE AND YOU'LL
SAVE YOUR OWN MONEY.
SCAMP SCAMPY, ON SALE.
THIS IS A GREAT DEAL THIS YOGURT
IS USUALLY $99, ON SALE FOR $60
CENTS, I HAVE A COUPON, TO I GET
FOUR.
NOW CORY, IF YOU MAKE A LIST AND
YOU MAKE A PLAN, YOU CAN AFFORD
TO BUY COFFEE, WITH A COUPON   .
LOTS OF STUFF.
GOOD, I HOPE YOU LIKE COUPONS.
>> HAVE A NICE DAY.
>> THANK YOU, YOU TOO.
KATIE: NICE JOB STEPHANIE.
ALL RIGHT.
SO IT'S AMAZING, ALL THIS FOR
$120.
BECAUSE WE SHOULD MENTION --
>> OH, NO, IT WAS $98.
OUR BUDGET WAS $120.
KATIE: OH WOW, AND WE SHOULD
MENTION $120 IS ABOUT THE
ALLOTMENT YOU GET FOR A FAMILY
OF FOUR ON FOOD STAMPS FOR A
WEEK.
SO, TELL US A LITTLE, SOME OF
MORE OF YOUR TIPS IF YOU COULD
STEPHANIE.
>> WELL THE NUMBER ONE IS YOU
HAVE TO HAVE A PLAN.
SO THE KEY IS DON'T WALK INTO
THE GROCERY STORE WITH A BUNCH
OF MENUS TO GET INGREDIENTS.
START WITH THAT STORE ADD AND
SEE WHAT THE ROCK BOTTOM DEALS
ARE AND MAKE YOUR MENU FOR THE
WEEK BASED ON WHAT'S ON SALE.
THAT WILL CUT YOUR COST
DRAMATIC.
KATIE: CORY AND I WERE TALKING
ABOUT THE FACT THAT A LOT OF
PEOPLE ARE SO BUSY, WORKING
HARD, TRYING TO TAKE CARE OF
THEIR FAMILIES.
SOMETIMES EVEN WORKING TWO JOBS.
IT SEEMS TO ME, STEPHANIE, THAT
ALL THE CUTTING AND CALCULATING
CAN BE PRETTY STRESSFUL.
HOW DO YOU REDUCE THAT?
>> THERE ARE EASY RESOURCES
ONLINE, COUPON MOM TELLS YOU
WHAT THE DEALS ARE, TELLS YOU
WHERE TO GET THE COUPONS, YOU
CAN PRINT COUPONS.
SO IF YOU CAN ALLOW HALF AN HOUR
FOR PLANNING FOR YOUR GROCERY
EACH WEEK, YOU CAN DO THIS.
IF YOU DON'T HAVE THAT MUCH
TIME, IF YOU WALK INTO THE
GROCERY STORE AND PICK UP THE
CIRCULAR, YOU'RE GOING TO SAVE
25% JUST DOING THAT.
KATIE: SO THIS IS REALLY DELUS
210 WORTH OF FOOD THAT YOU GOT
FOR $98.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
KATIE: USING COUPONS.
WOW, WHAT DO YOU THINK CORY?
>> I'M WONDERING IF I CAN GET
SOME OF THIS AS A PARTING GIFT
FOR GOING HOME.
NO, THIS IS EXTRAORDINARY.
KATIE: YOU SAID THE YOGURT COST
HOW MUCH?
>> .10.
WE EVEN HAVE GREEK YOGURT, WHICH
DON'T WE JUST O LOVE THAT?
KATIE: WOW.
WHAT ARE OTHER TIPS YOU CAN GIVE
US FOR PEOPLE WHO ARE FEEDING
THEMSELVES OR A WHOLE FAMILY ON
A BUDGET?
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
WE TALKED ABOUT PLANNING, PLAN
FOR LEFTOVERS SO YOU BUY THE
VALUE PACK OF PORK CHOPS, HAVE
ENOUGH FOR THE NEXT DAY FOR
SANDWICHES.
ALSO WANT TO MAKE SURE YOU'RE
BRAND FLEXIBLE, BUY THE BRAND ON
SALE OR THE STORE BRAND IF
THAT'S NOT THE BEST DEAL.
MAKE SURE YOU LOOK FOR COUPONS.
YOU CAN GET THEM IN THE
NEWSPAPER, ALSO PRINT THEM
ONLINE AND YOU CAN GET THEM
ELECTRONICALLY.
AND WE GOT SOME GOOD COUPONS
FROM THE STORE CIRCULAR JUST
WALKING IN.
>> DO COUPONS WORK AT A LOCAL
BODEGA?
>> IN MOST CASES YES, THEY'RE
PROBABLY NOT GOING TO DOUBLE THE
COUPON.
YOU TALKED ABOUT CHALLENGES WITH
GOING TO SUPERMARKETS, SOME OF
THE STRATEGIES WE TALKED ABOUT
THAT DON'T INVOLVE COUPONS CAN
SAVE YOU MONEY.
IN TERMS OF BEING BRAND FLEXIBLE
AND SOAKING PLANS.
AND REALLY PLANNING.
DID YOU KNOW 30% OF THE AVERAGE
GROCERY BILL IS WASTED JUST BY
NOT PLANNING FOR LEFTOVERS.
BY TEACHING PEOPLE PLANNING, WE
CAN HELP.
>> I EAT TWO THIRDS OF IT, AND
THEN IT GOES TO WASTE.
I THINK THERE'S A TREMENDOUS
AMOUNT OF FOOD WASTE IN THIS
COUNTRY RIGHT NOW BECAUSE PEOPLE
PROBABLY AREN'T PLANNING, LIKE
ME.
YOU MADE ME FEEL DUMB.
[LAUGHTER]
KATIE: THAT DOESN'T HAPPEN VERY
MUCH TO A RHODES SCHOLAR SO WE
FEEL FOR YOU.
>> NO, BUT THANK YOU.
THIS IS INCREDIBLE.
>> WE'LL GET TOGETHER.
KATIE: I THINK, IT REALLY IS
SUCH IMPORTANT INFORMATION.
STEPHANIE THANK YOU VERY MUCH
BECAUSE IT REALLY OPENED MY
EYES.
YOU SHOULD NEVER GO TO THE
GROCERY STORE HUNGRY, RIGHT?
>> OH, THAT'S RIGHT.
KATIE: BECAUSE YOU MAKE BAD
DECISIONS.
>> BUT TASTY DECISIONS.
[LAUGHTER]
KATIE: I KNOW CORY'S BIGGEST
CHALLENGE DURING THIS WHOLE WEEK
WAS WHEN YOU HAD TO HAVE A
MEETING AT A BAKERY --
>> YES.
KATIE: WOW, WHO DID YOU TICK OFF
THAT THEY HAD A MEETING IN A
BAKERY?
>> IT WAS A PREGNANT FRIEND OF
MINE WHO WANTED TO UPDATE ME ON
SOMETHINGS.
SO I YIELDED TO HER BEING WITH
CHILD AND HAVING A BIG APPETITE.
KATIE: BUT YOU COULDN'T BUY
ANYTHING?
>> I SAT THERE AND DRANK WATER
AS I WATCHED HER ENJOY A MEAL.
KATIE: YOU TWEETED SOMETHING?
>> I RAN BACK TO MY CAR AND
SCARFED DOWN PEACE AND CORN,
PRETENDING IT WAS CHRISTMAS
COOKIES.
KATIE: YOU SAID DELIVER US FROM
EVIL, RIGHT?
>> I WAS PRAYING, YES.
KATIE: THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
BRINGING AWARENESS TO THIS
ISSUE.
>> THANK YOU FOR BRINGING
AWARENESS TO THIS ISSUE.
KATIE: STEPHANIE, THANK YOU,
APPRECIATE IT.
DO YOU THINK YOU ALL KNOW HOW TO
SAVE AT THE SUPERMARKET?
YOU CAN TAKE OUR QUIZ AT KATIE
COURIC.COM AND EVERYONE IN OUR
AUDIENCE CAN BONE UP ON BARGAIN
HUNTING, YOU'RE ALL GETTING A
COPY OF STEPHANIE'S BOOK.
SO WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KATIE: THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
COMING, AS WE TOOK A LITTLE TRIP
TO THE GARDEN STATE TODAY.
A BIG THANK YOU TO THE CAST OF
"JERSEY SHORE," AND OF COURSE TO
NEWARK MAYOR CORY BOOKER.
A BIG THANK YOU TO ALL OF YOU
FOR WATCHING.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
>>> HEARD LOTS OF BANGS AND WE
THOUGHT IT WAS A CUSTODIAN
KNOCKING STUFF DOWN.
WE HEARD SCREAMING.
AND SO... WE -- WE, UM... WE
LOOKED TO THE WALL.
>> THAT WAS A 4th GRADER
DESCRIBING THE CHAOS AFTER A
GUNMAN OPENED FIRE AT A
CONNECTICUT ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
STUDENTS WERE ESCORTED OUT IN
A LINE WITH HANDS ON EACH
OTHER'S SHOULDERS.
GOOD EVENING, EVERYBODY.
I'M LARRY BEIL.
>> HERE IS THE LATEST ON THE
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT.
POLICE SAY THE SHOOTER KILLED
26 PEOPLE, THEN TOOK HIS OWN
LIFE.
THEY'RE NOW SAYING HE ALSO
KILLED HIS MOTHER INSIDE OF
HER HOME.
>> 20 OF THOSE KILLED ARE
CHILDREN.
SIX ADULTS WERE KILLED.
THE GUNMAN HAS BEEN IDENTIFIED
AS ADAM LANZA.
ONE ADULT KILLED WAS THE
SCHOOL PRINCIPAL, WHO
INSTALLED A NEW SECURITY
SYSTEM AT THE SCHOOL.
>> HERE IS A LIVE PICTURE OF A
CHURCH IN NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT.
PEOPLE WILL BE GATHERING IN
JUST A LITTLE BIT.
THEY'RE SHOWING UP THERE FOR A
VIGIL.
KE WE HAVE THE LATEST
DEVELOPMENTS ON THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY.
 GUNMAN WENT TO THE
SCHOOL TODAY ARMED WEARING A
BULLETPROOF VEST.
WE'RE LEARNING HIS MOTHER WAS
KILLED AT HER HOME BEFORE THAT
RAMPAGE BEGANFUL WE HAVE LEARN
THAT HAD THREE WEAPONS USED IN
THIS SHOOTING WERE REGISTERED
TO ADAM LANZA'S MOTHER,
PURCHASED LEGALLY.
THERE IS CONFUSION ABOUT
WHETHER HIS BROTHER WAS THE
GUNMAN.
POLICE SAY IS HE NOT THE
THE GUNMAN IDENTIFIED AS
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA. A
TRAGEDY IN A SMALL CONNECTICUT
COMMUNITY.
NUMBERS ARE STAGGERING.
20 OF THEM,
CHILDREN.
>> THIS IS JUST MIND BLOWING
AND UNBELIEVABLE.
>> POLICE SAY THE SHOOTER, A
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA STRUCK
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
FRIDAY MORNING.
>> THERE WERE SEVERAL
FATALITIES AT TH