>>> I'M CHERYL JENNINGS.
TODAY WE WANT TO SHOWCASE TWO
BELOVED ORGANIZATIONS IN THE BAY
AREA THAT HAS BROUGHT US THE JOY
OF DANCE AND MUSIC FOR DECADES.
ECONOMY IS TAKING A TOLL ON
THEIR BUDGETS SO WE ARE HOPING
YOU WILL HELP US PRESERVE THESE
CHERISHED TRADITIONS FOR
GENERATIONS TO COMB.
OUR FIRST GUEST CELEBRATING 35
YEARS NEXT YEAR.
SUSAN SA MI YA AND JULIE IS
EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR AND WE HAVE
THE ETHNIC ARTISTIC DIRECTOR.
LET ME START WITH YOU.
THE DANCE FESTIVAL IS
CELEBRATING 35 YEARS.
THAT IS GREAT.
CONGRATULATIONS, WHAT CAN WE
EXPECT?
>> THE SAN FRANCISCO ETHNIC
DANCE FESTIVAL IS LARGEST
MULTICULTURAL FESTIVAL IN THE
WORLD.
WE HAVE FOUR WEEKENDS IN JUNE.
EVERYONE IS IN COMPLETE COSTUME
AND TRADITION.
IT'S FAMILY FRIENDLY AND A
AFFORDABLE.
OVER 35 YEARS, WE ARE IN TOUCH
WITH OVER 450 DANCE GROUPS
REPRESENTING 100 CULTURES.
WE HAVE SHOWCASED OVER 25,000
DANCERS FROM THE AGE OF SIX TO
812.
IF YOU COME TO THE FESTIVAL YOU
CAN EXPECT TO TRAVEL AROUND THE
WORLD LEARNING ABOUT THE
CULTURES AND TRADITIONS THAT
MAKE SAN FRANCISCO SPECIAL.
>> Cheryl: ONE OF THOSE PEOPLE
THAT HAVE BEEN A LONG TIME C.K.
YOU ARE A PERFORMER AND YOU ARE
THE ARTISTIC DIRECTOR.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A LOOK AT
SOME OF THE PERFORMANCES WHAT
THE EXPERIENCE IS LIKE FOR YOU.
>> PERFORMING IN THE FESTIVAL IS
MUSIC AND DANCES EXPERT IS A
JOY.
>> Cheryl: YOU TEACH DANCE AT
U.C. BERKELEY?
>> I TEACH MUSIC.
I TEACH MUSIC AND YOU'LL BE
DANCING, TOO.
THE TWO ARE ONE AND SAME.
>> Cheryl: WHY IS IT SO
IMPORTANT TO BE PART OF THIS?
>> IN THE DIVERSE CULTURE
SHARING THE CULTURAL EXPERIENCES
IS A VERY IMPORTANT THING.
>> Cheryl: PEOPLE GET TO KNOW
EACH OTHER?
>> PEOPLE GET TO KNOW ONE
ANOTHER AND ALL THE STEREOTYPES
GET WIPED OUT.
WE CAN TALK TO EACH OTHER AND
KEEP THE PEACE AND BUILD THE
COMMUNITY.
>> Cheryl: THAT IS BEAUTIFULLY
SAID.
WE HAVE TO TALK ABOUT MONEY.
I KNOW THE BUDGET HAS BEEN A
STRUGGLE TO PUT THE EVENT ON.
>> IT STARTED WHEN THE ECONOMIC
DOWNTURN STARTED AND WE LOST
MONTH MOST OF OUR GOVERNMENT
FUNDING AND CORPORATE FUNDING.
IN 2011 WE GOT WORD THEY WERE
CLOSING THE PARKING LOT WITH THE
DOYLE DRIVE CONSTRUCTION
PROJECT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE 25 YEARS AND
NEW VENUES HAVE FEWER SEATS.
THOSE LOSS OF SEATS HAVE
TRANSLATED TO A HUNDRED THOUSAND
DOLLAR PER YEAR LOST INCOME
REVENUE WHICH HAS PUT US IN A
VERY DIFFICULT FINANCIAL
POSITION.
>> Cheryl: YOU HAD AUDITIONS?
>> THE AUDITIONS ARE A CRUCIAL
PART OF THE CULTURAL ECOLOGY FOR
HUNDREDS OF DASERS IN THE BAY
AREA.
>> Cheryl: WE'RE GOING TO TALK
ABOUT HOW PEOPLE CAN GET
INVOLVED IN THAT.
I WANT TO GO BACK TO SOMETHING
THAT C.K. SAID IT BRINGS
COMMUNITY TOGETHER.
YOUR GROUPS HAVE BEEN INVITED TO
PERFORM EVERYWHERE.
>> LAST YEAR WE WERE INVITED TO
PERFORM IN THE MAYOR'S
INAUGURATION AND WE RECEIVED THE
MAYOR'S 2012 AWARD WHICH WAS SO
EXCITING.
NED UP TL BENED UP TOANY VENUE
SHARING A TRADITION IN THE
CULTURE.
WE HAVE THOUSANDS OF DANCERS
THAT WOULD LOVE TO RETAIN THEIR
CULTURE AND TEACH THEIR
TRADITIONS THROUGH MUSIC AND
DANCE AND COME UP TO THE
COMMUNITY AND BUILD BRIDGES
WITHIN EACH OTHER AND TO EACH
OTHER.
IT'S BECOME A NETTING.
>> I WANT TO TALK ABOUT THE KIDS
PROGRAM YOU STARTED AND HOW
PEOPLE CAN GET INVOLVED AND HELP
SAVING THE ETHNIC DANCE
FESTIVAL.
WE'RE GOING TO COME BACK.
MORE ABOUT THE ETHNIC DANCE
FESTIVAL.
STAY WITH US AND WE'LL BE RI(Kx
>> Cheryl: WELCOME BACK TO
"BEYOND THE HEADLINES".
WE WERE TALKING ABOUT PRESERVING
THE ARTS.
SAN FRANCISCO ETHNIC DANCE
FESTIVAL.
SUSAN AND JULIE AND C.K. ARE
HERE WITH US TODAY.
I LOVE THE ETHNIC DANCE
FESTIVAL.
I'VE BEEN THERE FOR MANY YEARS
AND YOU HAVE A CHILDREN'S
PROGRAM.
YOU WANT TO TELL US ABOUT IT.
>> PROGRAM IS CALLED KIDS UNITED
THROUGH DANCE.
IT'S A PILOT PROGRAM.
WE KNOW THAT THE KIDS ARE THE
FUTURE.
GETTING THEM INVOLVED IN DANCE
EARLY.
SO THIS PROGRAM AND KIDS COME
AND DANCERS FROM GHANA.
THE COMBINATION AND THEY PERFORM
THAT IS THE PICTURE WE SEE RIGHT
NOW.
IT WAS ONE GREAT PROGRAM.
>> Cheryl: AND KIDS LEARN TO
WORK TOGETHER.
>> THEY LEARN TO DANCE WITH ONE
ANOTHER AND LEARN NEW CULTURE.
I WAS DOWN THERE PERFORMING.
>> Cheryl: I WANTED TO SEE YOU
PERFORM.
I WANT TO ASK YOU ABOUT THE
PROGRAMS THAT YOU CREATE FOR THE
DANCE FESTIVAL OVER THE SUMMER.
IT HAPPENS IN JUNE, HOW DO YOU
DO THAT?
>> FIRST OF ALL, THE FESTIVAL
STARTS IN JANUARY WITH
AUDITIONS.
WE HAVE PEOPLE THAT SELECT
COMPANIES AND THEN WE PICK THOSE
AND DESIGN THE PROGRAM FOR ALL
THE WEEKS OF THE FESTIVAL.
>> Cheryl: A LOT OF WORK.
BEFORE WE RUN OUT OF TIME, JULIE
YOU WERE TALKING ABOUT THE
SEVERE FINANCIAL CHALLENGES.
HOW CAN PEOPLE HELP?
I KNOW YOU CAME UP WITH A
CREATIVE PROGRAM CALLED THE
PRODUCERS CIRCLE?
>> WE ARE TRYING TO FIND NEW
REVENUES AND FOR $250 AN
INDIVIDUAL CAN BECOME AN A
MEMBER OF PRODUCER'S CIRCLE AND
THEY GET TO THE AUDITIONS AND
PARTIES AND OTHER PERKS.
IF WE CAN FIND 400 PEOPLE TO
BECOME PRODUCERS, THEN WE CAN
KEEP THE FESTIVAL GOING.
SO, TWO YEARS IT HAS TRANSLATED
INTO A HUNDRED THOUSAND DOLLAR
LOSS.
>> Cheryl: WE NEED SOMEBODY TO
ADOPT THE FESTIVAL.
>> WE NEED AN ANGEL INVESTOR.
>> AND FESTIVAL IS AFFORDABLE
FOR FAMILIES?
>> OUR AUDITIONS, ADMISSION FEE
IS $10 AND YOU WILL BE ABLE TO
COME TO FOUR DAYS OF NONSTOP
PERFORM ANSWERS FROM MANY DANCE
TROUPES.
CHILDREN ARE FREE.
WE ARE LOOKING FOR A SPONSOR TO
STEP FORWARD SO WE CAN ALSO
BRING CHILDREN IN FREE TO THE
FESTIVAL.
RIGHT NOW WE HAVE VERY
ATTRACTIVE RATES STARTING FROM
$12 ON AN AVERAGE UP TO 48 ON
THE HIGH END.
THEY ARE VERY AFFORDABLE.
>> SO HAVE YOU SEEN FAVORITE
MOMENTS AT THE FESTIVAL.
>> MY FAVORITE MOMENTS IS ALL
THE DANCERS ARE BACKSTAGE IN
THEIR COSTUMES WITH THEIR LIVE
MUSIC AND THEY ARE TEACHING EACH
OTHER THEIR DANCES AND THEIR
CULTURES AND PUTTING TOGETHER
COLLABORATIONS BACKSTAGE.
WE SEE THAT TRANSLATED NOW AS
SOME OF THE GROUPS ARE FORMING
PERFORM BEFORE THE FESTIVAL
COLLABORATING WITH THEIR
CULTURES.
WE FEEL THIS IS WHAT THE
FESTIVAL, ONE OF THE HIGHLIGHTS
OF WHAT THE FESTIVAL CAN REALLY
DO.
>> Cheryl: YOU WANTED TO SAY
SOMETHING?
>> BACKSTAGE IN THE FESTIVAL.
I'M SORRY THAT THE AUDIENCE
CAN'T EXPERIENCE THAT.
THE PEOPLE COME TOGETHER TO
TEACH EACH OTHER AND MAKING
MUSIC.
>> Cheryl: WE'VE GOT 30 SECONDS
LEFT?
>> AFTER THE SHOW THAT HAPPENS
IN JUNE, THE ARTISTS COME OUT TO
THE LOBBY AND THEN THE DANCE AND
SING WITH THE AUDIENCE.
I THINK FROM THE AUDIENCE SURVEY
THAT HAS BEEN ONE OF THE MOST
BELOVED MOMENTS.
WE KEPT THAT FOR EACH SHOW
THROUGHOUT THE YEARS TO GIVE
PEOPLE AN UPCLOSE AND PERSONAL
INTERACTION.
KIDS ASK FOR AUTOGRAPHS AND KIDS
WILL PERFORM WITH EACH OTHER.
IT'S A MAGICAL MOMENT.
IT'S A RARE CHANCE TO EXPERIENCE
FIRSTHAND THE CULTURE HERE IN
THE BAY AREA THAT WE ARE SO
LUCKY TO HAVE.
>> Cheryl: WE HAVE ALL THE
INFORMATION ON OUR WEBSITE FOR
EVERYBODY AT HOME SO THEY CAN
LEARN MORE INFORMATION IF THEY
WANT TO DONATE OR PARTICIPATE.
THANK YOU ALL FOR BEING HERE.
WE DO HAVE TO TAKE A BREAK.
FIND OUT MORE ABOUT THE
AUDITIONS AND PRODUCERS CIRCLE
AT ABC7NEWS.COM.
WHEN WE COME BACK YOU WILL MEET
MEMBERS OF THE OAKLAND BALLET.
THEY ARE REACHING OUT TO THE
COMMUNITY.
STAY WITH US.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
♪
[ Boy 1 ] Hey!
That's the last Crescent.
Oh, did you want it?
Yea
We'll split it.
[ Female Announcer ]
Made fresh, so light,
buttery and flakey.
That's half
That's not half!
Guys, I have more!
Thanks Mom
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Crescents.
Let the Making Begin
[ Female Announcer ]
HOLIDAY COOKIES ARE A BIG JOB.
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE
JUST RIGHT.
PERFECTION IS IN THE DETAILS.
♪
GET TO HOLIDAY FUN FASTER
WITH PILLSBURY COOKIE DOUGH.
>> Cheryl: WELCOME BACK TO
"BEYOND THE HEADLINES".
TODAY WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
PRESERVING THE ARTS.
BAY AREA'S RICH TRADITIONS
INCLUDE THE OAKLAND BALLET THAT
HAS BEEN AROUND FOR 45 YEARS
WITH A DEEP COMMITMENT TO KEEP
IT EXCITING AND ACCESSIBLE TO
THE COMMUNITY.
OUR GUESTS IS THE OAKLAND'S
BALLET PRINCIPAL AND BOBBY,
INTERNATIONALLY ACCLAIMED DANCER
AND CHOREOGRAPHER.
I HAD A CHANCE TO MEET YOU A
COUPLE YEARS AGO.
I HAVE BEEN HOOKED EVER SINCE.
I LOVED YOUR PRODUCTION OF THE
NUTCRACKER.
YOU ARE WITH THE BALLET BUT IT
DOES A LOT OF STUFF.
>> WE'RE DOING MUCH MORE THAN
THE NUTCRACKER.
CLEARLY IT IS OUR FOCUS THIS
TIME OF THE YEAR, GETTING THE
STUDENTS READY AND WORKING WITH
THE ORCHESTRA AND MAIN FOCUS
RIGHT NOW, WE HAVE ONGOING
SATURDAY BALLET CLASSES.
WE HAVE A PROGRAM IN THE SPRING
AND WE HAVE A TWO WEEK SUMMER
PROGRAM FOR YOUNG DANCERS HELD
AT NORTH COLLEGE.
>> Cheryl: I KNOW YOU HAVE
PROGRAMS THAT ARE ACCESSIBLE TO
THE COMMUNITY?
>> ONE OF THE REASONS I FOUND
THE COMPANY IS SO PASSIONATE, WE
HAVE 1400 STUDENTS COMING TO
DRESS REHEARSAL AND GIVEN MORE
THAN THOUSAND TICKETS AWAY TO
SCHOOLS.
>> Cheryl: FOR THOSE THAT DON'T
KNOW, HOW ABOUT THE MUSIC.
>> MANY PEOPLE HAVE A GREAT
FAMILIARITY WITH IT.
I NEVER HAD TO DANCE IN THE
PIECE.
WHEN I CAME TO CHOREOGRAPH I WAS
IN LOVE WITH EVERY SECOND.
IT'S.
>> AND YOU HAVE THE OAKLAND EAST
BAY SYMPHONY.
>> Cheryl: NOW WE HAVE THE
BEAUTIFUL DANCERS WITH US.
I WANT TO START WITH YOU.
YOU LOOK ABSOLUTELY GORGEOUS.
HOW DO YOU DO IT AND WHY ARE YOU
INVOLVED WITNESS?
>> IT'S BEEN A DREAM AND I'M SO
EXCITED.
TECHNICALLY THE MOST CHALLENGING
IN THE PRODUCTION IN PERFECTING
THAT AND IT IS ALSO -- WHAT YOU
CARRY FROM RESPONSIBILITY TO BE
AN EXAMPLE TO THEM AND INSPIRE
THEM TO DANCE AS WELL LIKE I WAS
INSPIRED AS A YOUNG CHILD.
>> Cheryl: BOBBY, WHAT IS THE
ROLE AND WHAT HO GOT YOU INTO
THIS?
>> IT'S REALLY GREAT.
THEY HAVE CREATED A WONDERFUL
VARIATION AND VERY CHALLENGING
BUT I THINK IT IS GREAT BECAUSE
IT HELPS US GET BETTER.
IT'S REALLY FUN AND WONDERFUL.
>> Cheryl: HOW DID YOU GET
INVOLVED WITH THIS WITH DANCE?
>> FIRST TIME I SAW A MUSIC
VIDEO.
THEN I HAD PERFORMERS COME TO MY
SCHOOL WHEN I WAS A LITTLE KID
DIPLOMA.
>> AND BALLET GOES TO SCHOOLS?
>> YES.
>> Cheryl: I KNOW YOU HAVE TO
GET UP EARLY FOR THAT?
>> ONCE YOU ARE THERE AND YOU
ARE DOING WHAT YOU ARE DOING AND
YOU SEE THESE LITTLE FACES AT
8:30 AND 9:00 IT GOES OUT THE
WINDOW.
YOUR WHOLE IF INSPIRING
THESE KIDS AND GIVING THEM
SOMETHING ELSE IS A BIT MORE
HIGHER ON THE PRIORITY.
>> Cheryl: THERE IS SO MANY WAYS
BALLET HELPS THE COMMUNITY.
HOSPITALS AND OTHER PLACES.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
IT'S A VERY BROAD BASED ACTIVITY
BUT GOING INTO THE SCHOOLS AS WE
DO IS VERY MOVING.
LAST YEAR ONE OF THE PRINCIPALS
ASKED BROKE DOWN AND CRIED.
WE NEVER GET THIS KIND OF THING.
THEY ARE VERY PASSIONATE ABOUT
WHAT WE DO.
>> Cheryl: AND SO MANY KIDS HAVE
THE OPPORTUNITY TO GET OUT THERE
PERFORMING AT PARAMOUNT THEATER?
>> IT'S GORGEOUS AND I STEP ON
STAGE AND THE THEATER WITH ALL
THE HISTORY AND GOLD WALLS AND
ALL THE FACES IN ANTICIPATION IS
VERY EXCITING.
>> IS IT INTIMIDATING A LITTLE
BIT?
>> I GET BUTTERFLIES BEFORE I GO
ON.
>> Cheryl: WE HAVE A LOT MORE TO
TALK ABOUT.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A BREAK.
WHEN WE COME BACK, WE'RE GOING
TO FIND OUT WHY THE OAKLAND
BALLET IS FACING SERIOUS
FINANCIAL CHALLENGES.
STAY WITH
You know how much Grandma
wanted to be here
for your fist Christmas?
You see
Grandma lives waaaay down here,
and you live way up here.
Brian, your cousin, he's
a little bit older than you,
he lives here, in Chicago.
And your Aunt Lisa lives here,
in Baltimore.
Uncle Earnie?
Waaay out in Hawaii.
But don't you worry,
we will always be together
for Christmas.
[ Male Announcer ]
Being together
is the best part
of the holidays
and Cheerios is happy
to be part of the family.
You just ate Dallas!
>> Cheryl: WELCOME BACK.
OUR GUESTS ARE FROM THE OAKLAND
BALLET.
ARTISTIC DIRECTOR AND DANCER AND
BOBBY BRISCO.
RAIN I ATTENDED A BOARD MEETING
WITH SOME OF THE FOLKS TO LEARN
ABOUT THE FINANCIAL CHALLENGES
FACING THE BALLET.
CAN YOU TELL US A LITTLE BIT
ABOUT THAT.
>> SOME OF YOUR EARLIER GUESTS
WERE TALKING ABOUT DRASTIC CUTS.
SO WE'RE TRYING TO HANG IN THERE
AND BE CAREFUL ABOUT WHAT WE DO.
WE HAVE CREATED PROGRAMS LIKE
THE POWER OF MANY WHERE ITS
PROGRAM WHERE WE'RE TRYING TO
RAISE $50,000 WITH 1,000 GIFTS
OF $50.
WE HAVE RAISED $23,000.
PACKAGES BEGIN AT HUNDRED
DOLLARS AND YOU CAN COME AND SEE
THE NUT CRACKER AND PLACE AN AD
IN OUR PLAY BILL.
WE ARE GRATEFUL FOR YOUR SUPPORT
AND TELLING FOLKS HOW YOU CAN
HELP US.
I THINK WE ARE FACING SOME
SERIOUS DECISIONS.
BOARD IS THERE TO HELP US.
THEY ARE TRYING TO RAISE MONEY
AND THAT IS WHAT THE BOARD
PRIMARILY DOES.
>> Cheryl: LET'S TALK A LITTLE
MORE WITH OUR DANCERS HOW THIS
AFFECTS YOU.
CHANTELLE HOW HAS THIS AFFECTED
YOUR LIFE.
DID YOU START WITH THE BALLET
HERE OR ANOTHER BALLET?
>> I STARTED TRAINING AS A YOUNG
GIRL IN THE EAST BAY AND THEN
MOVED TO THE SCHOOL AND THEN
WENT TO THE NEW YORK.
AS I GOT OLDER AND GRADUATED I
CAME BACK TO THE BAY AREA AND
CURRENTLY DANCING WITH OAKLAND
BALLET.
THIS IS MY THIRD WITH THEM.
IT'S BEEN A PLEASANT EXPERIENCE.
>> Cheryl: HAS IT CHANGED AT
ALL?
>> I FEEL SO GRATEFUL THAT I'M
ABLE TO WORK AND MY PASSION IS
ONE AND THE SAME THAT HAS THAT
LUXURY.
TO ME IT'S VERY REWARDING TO ME.
>> Cheryl: YOU GET TO DO WHAT
YOU LOVE?
>> EXACTLY.
I STARTED AT 15ERFORMING PERFORN
HIGH SCHOOL.
THE SAME, I'VE HAD THE LUXURY OF
DANCING NOT ONLY IN AMERICA BUT
INTERNATIONALLY.
TO GO BACK AND TALK ABOUT SCHOOL
I'M ABLE TO GO INTO THESE
SCHOOLS AND SHARE MY ART FORM
AND HOPEFULLY INSPIRE PEOPLE NOT
BECAUSE THEY HAVE TO BUT BECAUSE
THEY WANT TO.
>> Cheryl: GRAHAM, I WAS
THINKING ABOUT HOW DIFFERENTLY
YOUR NUTCRACKER IS.
WHY IS IT SO DIFFERENT?
>> IT'S A LATER PERIOD,
EDWARDIAN PERIOD.
I HAVE SNOWBALLS AND CANDY COOKS
AND AN OPPORTUNITY FOR YOUNG
PEOPLE.
WE HAVE 50 PEOPLE AND IT'S PART
OF THEIR EDUCATION.
SOME OF THEM ARE ON STAGE FOR
THE FIRST OR SECOND TIME.
THEY HAVE EIGHT MINUTES ON STAGE
SO IT'S VERY EXCITING TO SEE
THEM, GRASP THEIR ROLE AND TAKE
IT JUST LIKE THE PROFESSIONALS.
>> Cheryl: HOW DO THEY GET TO BE
PART OF IT?
>> THEY AUDITIONED AND THE
COSTUMES COME IN.
ITS PUZZLE AND IT ALL COMES
TOGETHER WITH THE ORCHESTRA AND
LIGHTS GO DOWN.
IT REALLY IS AMAZING AND THE
ENJOYMENT FOR EVERYBODY.
>> Cheryl: DO YOU GET
BUTTERFLIES OR MADE A MISTAKE?
>> I MAKE PLENTY OF MISTAKES ON
THE STAGE.
THE KEY IS TO DEAL WITH IT AT
THE MOMENT.
IF SOMETHING IS DIFFERENT IN
REHEARSAL AND YOU MAKE IT WORK
AND CARRY ON.
THAT IS WHAT IT WILL BE FOR THAT
DAY.
>> IN THAT MOMENT AND MISTAKE
HAPPENS, OKAY, NOW WE'RE REALLY
LIGHTS ON.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Cheryl: WE'VE GOT 30 SECONDS
LEFT.
YOU GET ALL THESE PEOPLE
TOGETHER?
>> THERE IS SUCH A GOOD ENERGY
IN THE ROOM, I FIND IT JUST VERY
PLEASURABLE TO WORK WITH THEM
AND PROFESSIONALS.
IT'S SUCH A PRIVILEGE FOR ME AND
SEE THEIR ARTISTRY DEVELOP AND
BRING THAT TO THE PUBLIC.
I COULDN'T BE MORE GRATEFUL AND
PRIVILEGED.
>> Cheryl: YOU DO GET TO WATCH
THEM GROW?
>> IT'S WONDERFUL.
>> Cheryl: WE'RE GOING TO PUT
THE INFORMATION ABOUT THE
OAKLAND BALLET FOR EVERYONE AT
HOME.
CONGRATULATIONS, I CAN'T WAIT TO
SEE THE PERFORMANCE.
BIG THANK YOU TO ALL OF OUR
GUESTS TODAY.
THAT IS IT FOR THIS EDITION FOR
"BEYOND THE HEADLINES."
ALL OF OUR INFORMATION, YOU CAN
FIND IT ON OUR WEBSITE AT
ABC7NEWS.COM/COMMUNITY.
AND FIND US ON FACEBOOK AND ALSO
FOLLOW ME ON TWITTER.
I'M CHERYL JENNINGS.
HAVE A GREAT WEEK AND WE'LL SEE
YOU NEXT TIME.
AND...
TAKE CARE OF THEM,
YOU KNOW?
I FEEL LIKE WE'VE
COME FULL CIRCLE.
LIKE THAT!
THIS IS HOW
I'LL DO IT.
Sarah:
THERE YOU GO.
[ Female Announcer ]
At Yoplait,
we want you to feel
even better
about your favorite flavors.
So when you call, tweet,
and post, we listen.
That's why Yoplait Light
and Yoplait Original
are now made with
no high fructose corn syrup.
And why we use
only natural colors
and natural flavors
in Yoplait Original.
So, anything else we can do
for you, let us know.
But you'll keep it
to yogurt, right?
'Cause we shouldn't really help
with your love life.
Yoplait. It is so good!
♪
♪ RIGHT NOW, THE GOLDEN
GLOBE NOMINATIONS!
>> ELLEN MIR IN.
>> ZERO DARK THIRTY.
>> HOMELAND.
>> HUGH JACKMAN, THE
HOLLYWOOD STAR.
>> THIS IS COME HATLY
SURREAL.
>> BARBRA STREISAND TALKS
ROAD TRIPS!
>> IT WAS REALLY FUN.
>> 'S GLAD I IT DID.
>> AND HAVING FUN WITH A TV
PRESIDENT.
>> IT IS KIND OF LIKE
PULLING BACK THE COVERS, YOU
KNOW.
>> WE'RE ROLLING THE RED
CARPET NOW.
>> HI, I'M BILL PULMAN AND
YOU ARE WATCHING ON THE RED
CARPET.
♪
>> WELCOME TO ON THE RED
CARPET FROM THE SET