GET ME THROUGH THE BLOCKADE.
THEY'VE TAKEN HER SOMEWHERE,
AND I'M GONNA FIND HER.
♪
-- Captions by VITAC --
THREE DAYS, FOUR AT MOST.
IF IT TAKES A WEEK, THEN--
IT WON'T TAKE A WEEK.
IT CAN'T.
(alarm sounds)
NOW YOU OWE ME NOTHING, SAM,
AND YOU NEVER HAVE.
YOU UNDERSTAND
WHAT I'M SAYING?
BRING HER HOME SAFE.
(horns honking)
(bleating)
COME ON, BULLFROG.
DON'T BE THAT GUY.
(man) KING?
DAMN, SON.
I FIGURED YOU FOR SHARK CHUM
BY NOW.
(chuckles) EASY, MAN.
OH, THAT'S RIGHT.
I FORGOT WHAT
A DELICATE FLOWER YOU ARE.
YOU KNOW, YOUR FRIEND...
COME ON INSIDE.
(bleating continues)
(sighs)
(door closes)
SO THIS IS WHAT YOU LEFT
THE PARTY FOR?
IT'S, UH, GREAT.
WELL, IT BEATS THAT MARK V
WE SPENT EIGHT DAYS ON
IN THE GULF.
NO.
THIS IS WHY I LEFT
THE PARTY.
(chuckles)
(kisses)
WES, MY FRIEND HERE--
HOLD ON A SECOND, OKAY?
SWEETIE, CAN YOU TAKE CHARLIE
FOR A WALK?
THAT OKAY WITH YOU, KID?
YOU WANT TO GO
TO THE PARK WITH YOUR MOM,
GET SOME ICE CREAM?
MM-HMM.
IT'S OKAY.
(door opens)
I MEAN, WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU
THINKING, BRINGING HIM HERE?
LISTEN...
HUH?
I KNOW IT'S A BIG ASK.
I WOULDN'T BE HERE
IF IT WASN'T IMPORTANT.
WE NEED SOME INFORMATION,
AND THEN WE ARE GONE.
YOU HAVE GOT TO BE KIDDING ME.
YOU DO KNOW YOU'RE PUBLIC ENEMY
NUMBER TWO, RIGHT?
YES, I DO.
AND YOU COME TO MY HOUSE
IN BROAD DAYLIGHT.
NOW YOU WANT ME TO OPEN UP
OLD SOURCES?
THEY'VE GOT MY WIFE.
SHE WAS RENDITIONED
TWO DAYS AGO
OFF THE THE ISLAND
OF SAINTE MARINA.
MANILA'S THE CLOSEST
WAY STATION.
YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
WE DON'T HAVE A LOT OF TIME.
WAIT. HOLD ON A SECOND.
TWO DAYS AGO?
LOOK, I'M SORRY, MAN.
SHE'S ALREADY GONE.
OH, NO.
DON'T--DON'T--DON'T--
DON'T TELL ME SHE'S GONE.
SHE'S NOT GONE.
RENDITION LIKE THIS
USUALLY TAKES
AT LEAST THREE DAYS
TO ARRANGE TRANSFER.
THAT MEANS I GOT ABOUT 12 HOURS
BEFORE THEY THROW HER
IN SOME HOLE SOMEWHERE.
YOU UNDERSTAND ME?
YEAH. WELL, GOOD LUCK
WITH THAT.
HEY.
I SUGGEST YOU TELL YOUR FRIEND
TO TAKE HIS DAMN HANDS
OFF ME.
I'M SORRY IF THIS IS
INCONVENIENT FOR YOU,
BUT THEY GOT MY WIFE.
SO IF YOU CAN HELP US,
I DON'T HAVE THE LUXURY
OF LETTING YOU SAY NO.
I HAVE A WIFE, TOO.
OKAY.
OKAY? AND A KID
ON TOP OF THAT.
ANYBODY FIND OUT I MADE
CONTACT WITH YOU,
I AM BACK ON THE GRID.
I'M JUST TRYING TO PROTECT
MY FAMILY, SAME AS YOU.
(sighs) OH, MAN.
(exhales) YOU REALLY STOLE
A U.S. BOOMER?
IT SORT OF JUST HAPPENED,
YEAH.
(laughs)
(sighs deeply)
OKAY.
JUST... LOOK...
YOU'RE GONNA NEED
10K FOR BRIBES.
AND THEN THERE'S CASH FOR
ACCESS, EQUIPMENT, EXTRACTION.
I MEAN, I'M GUESSING YOU GUYS
DON'T HAVE 50 BUCKS BETWEEN YOU.
YEAH, YOU'D BE SURPRISED
WHAT I CAN GET MY HANDS ON.
(people speaking indistinctly)
YOU. MOVE THE CRATES.
LET'S GO.
WHAT DO YOU WANT FROM ME?
ME? I DON'T WANT ANYTHING.
I'M JUST A BAGGAGE HANDLER.
YOU WORK FOR THE GOVERNMENT.
THEY PAY ME,
BUT I WOULDN'T SAY
I WORK FOR 'EM.
HERE.
GET CLEANED UP
BEFORE THE TRANSFER.
TRANSFER TO WHERE?
ABOVE MY PAY GRADE.
ONCE YOU'RE
OUT OF THIS BUILDING,
YOU'RE SOMEBODY ELSE'S PROBLEM.
DO YOU EVEN KNOW
WHO I AM?
I WATCH THE NEWS.
SIX HOURS.
YOU LEAVE IN SIX HOURS.
(pants)
(sniffles and cries)
(alarm sounding)
(radio clicks)
CAPTAIN MARCUS CHAPLIN
IS HERE NOW.
(click)
(man) Captain Marcus Chaplin,
I am Zheng Li, special envoy
from the People's Republic
of China.
It is China's understanding
that the current embargo
has eradicated your food
and medical supplies.
The government of China
considers this
a humanitarian crisis,
and I wish to come
to your shores.
TROJAN HORSE?
WE HAVE TO ASSUME SO.
(click)
PERMISSION TO COME ASHORE
GRANTED, MR. ZHENG.
(clicks)
(beeping)
U.S. VESSELS NOT ENGAGING.
SO MAYBE THE BLOCKADE
ISN'T A BLOCKADE
IF A COUNTRY LIKE CHINA
SAYS IT ISN'T.
GRACE, ORGANIZE A CONTINGENT
TO GREET MR. ZHENG.
THEY MAY COME IN PEACE,
BUT LET'S BE PREPARED.
YES, SIR.
(panting)
(groans)
OHH!
(grunts)
(exhales deeply)
(pants)
(motor whirring)
HE'LL BOW SLIGHTLY,
AND THEN YOU'LL SHAKE HANDS.
END OF MEETING.
SORRY, SIR.
I LEARNED IT FROM MY DAD
WHEN HE WAS AN ENVOY IN CHINA.
I WASN'T SURE
YOU KNEW THE PROTOCOL.
WELCOME TO SAINTE MARINA.
THANK YOU, CAPTAIN.
I'M VERY PLEASED TO BE HERE.
YOU HAVE A BEAUTIFUL ISLAND.
PLEASE.
(pants)
OH. (exhales)
(brakes squeal)
(turns off engine)
HAWKES?
(jeep door closes)
ONE MOMENT.
MY SISTER'S DEAD.
YES.
I'M SORRY.
I'M A DESERTER.
I LEFT THE LIEUTENANT
IN THE MIDDLE OF A FIREFIGHT.
YOU'RE GONNA ARREST ME
AND STRIP ME OF MY RANK, RIGHT?
SO WHY ARE YOU EVEN BOTHERING
TO TALK ABOUT HER?
BECAUSE I'M TRULY SORRY
SHE'S DEAD.
DON'T ACT LIKE YOU CARE
ABOUT HER, MAN.
DON'T DO THAT.
I'M GOING.
PETTY OFFICER HAWKES,
STOP.
SON, I'M SORRY.
BUT YOU ARE CHARGED
WITH DESERTION
AND CONDUCT UNBECOMING.
PETTY OFFICER BRANNAN.
SIR.
ARREST THIS MAN.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
CHARLIE.
THAT WAS MY DAD'S
DAD'S NAME.
I NEVER MET HIM.
SAY, CHARLIE.
PLAY NOW WITH YOUR FRIENDS.
OKAY.
GOOD JOB, KID.
(exhales deeply)
HOW LONG
HAVE YOU BEEN MARRIED?
UH, TWO YEARS.
WE'VE BEEN MARRIED TWO YEARS.
BUT I'VE BEEN AWAY MOST OF
THE TIME WE'VE BEEN TOGETHER.
MM-HMM.
AH, THAT'S THE LIFE
OF A SAILOR.
THAT'S ONE OF THE REASONS
I GOT OUT.
OH.
I MEAN, GOD KNOWS,
IT HASN'T BEEN EASY,
BUT--BUT EVERY TIME
I LOOK AT HER...
OH.
I KNOW IT WAS WORTH IT.
(exhales deeply)
HOW'D YOU GUYS MEET?
(chuckles)
I WAS AT A NAVY BAR
WITH SOME GUYS
OUT OF MIRAMAR.
THIS GROUP OF U.S.D. STUDENTS
COME IN. BIG GUYS.
THE MINUTE
THEY WALK IN THE DOOR,
YOU JUST--YOU KNOW
IT'S GONNA GO WRONG.
MM-HMM.
AND THEY GOT THIS, UH,
THEY GOT THIS GIRL WITH 'EM.
(chuckles)
AND I JUST--
I CAN'T STOP STARING AT HER.
OF COURSE,
IT DOES GO WRONG.
YOU KNOW... PEOPLE YELLING,
THROWING PUNCHES.
IN THE MIDDLE OF IT,
I WALK RIGHT UP TO HER,
AND I SAY, "HI, I'M SAM.
SAM KENDAL."
AND SHE STOPS ME.
AND SHE SAYS, "YES."
(chuckles)
"YES, SAM KENDAL,
I'D LOVE TO."
OH.
THAT'S PRETTY GOOD, THAT.
YOU KNOW, SHE DIDN'T ASK
FOR ANY OF THIS.
I MEAN, MARRYING ME,
SHE'S BEEN--BEEN DRAGGED
HALFWAY AROUND THE WORLD,
KIDNAPPED,
SCARED OUT OF HER MIND.
(sighs)
LOOK, SAM, I...
I SAID I'D GET INTO THIS.
I MEAN,
I'LL SET UP A MEET.
BUT YOU GOTTA DO SOMETHING
FOR ME.
YOU GOTTA PROMISE ME
THAT IF THIS THING
GOES SIDEWAYS, YOU GET CAUGHT,
YOU WERE NEVER HERE.
I PROMISE.
(Kylie) CHRISTINE KENDAL.
SOMEWHERE BETWEEN SAINTE MARINA
AND SYDNEY, SHE DISAPPEARED.
NO, NOT "GOT LOST."
DISAPPEARED,
AS IN "BLACK BAG DISAPPEARED."
OH. OH, NOW YOU'RE JUST GONNA
LIE TO MY FACE?
SHE WAS ON THE BOAT,
YOU SON OF A BITCH.
(beeps)
(sighs deeply)
CAROLINE, HI.
I JUST GOT OFF THE PHONE
WITH BILL SIMMS,
WHO YOU'RE GONNA FIRE
BY THE END OF THE DAY.
SO I'M TRYING TO TRACK DOWN
A PASSENGER--
I'M NOT HERE TO HURT YOU.
(both grunt)
(cell phone beeps)
AAH! NO!
AAH!
I TOLD YOU,
I WASN'T GONNA HURT YOU.
PLEASE, PLEASE, PLEASE, PLEASE!
I HAVE A LOT OF MONEY.
NO. NO, ST-STOP.
I CAN GET YOU A LOT OF MONEY.
MY NAME IS NAVY S.E.A.L.
BARRY HOPPER.
I WAS PICKED UP
OFF THE COAST OF PAKISTAN
BY THE U.S.S. "COLORADO."
I THINK YOU KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED NEXT.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
THIS IS THE HELMET CAM VIDEO
OF OUR MISSION IN PAKISTAN
RIGHT BEFORE WE NUKED IT.
THIS IS WHAT THE WHITE HOUSE
DOESN'T WANT ANYONE ELSE TO SEE.
IT'S YOURS FOR SOME OF
THAT MONEY YOU MENTIONED.
AND THIS IS
THE NOKIA LUMIA 920 FROM AT&T.
IT'S GOT LIVE TILES
SO ALL MY STUFF'S
ALWAYS RIGHT THERE IN REAL-TIME.
IT'S LIKE
THE ULTIMATE PERSONAL ASSISTANT.
BUT I'M ME,
AND ME NEEDS HANDLERS.
SO I HIRED TODD
TO HANDLE IT FOR ME.
TODD, GIMME THAT HOLLYWOOD NEWS!
WHAT'S HAPPENING ON TWITTER?
YOU'RE TRENDING!
YES!
YOU CAN'T HAVE A TODD,
BUT YOU CAN HAVE YOUR
OWN PERSONAL ASSISTANT.
I GUESS
YOU COULD CALL IT TODD.
[ Male Announcer ] THE NEW
NOKIA LUMIA 920 WITH LIVE TILES
THAT DELIVER WHAT YOU WANT
IN REAL TIME.
ONLY FROM AT&T.
RETHINK POSSIBLE.
THAT DELIVER WHAT YOU WANT
IN REAL TIME.
For thos...this...ions of doing
this...
...and this,
dancing in their heads...
...we have these.
Home Depot gift cards.
Give the gift of doing,
in-store or online.
MAKE A WISH!
I WISH WE COULD
LIE HERE FOREVER.
I WISH THIS TEST DRIVE WAS OVER,
SO WE COULD HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP.
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
TEST DRIVE!
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A JETTA.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN,
$0 DUE AT SIGNING, $0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
CAMPBELL'S HAS 24 NEW SOUPS
THAT WILL MAKE IT DROP OVER,
AND OVER AGAIN.
♪
FROM JAMMIN' JERK CHICKEN,
TO CREAMY GOUDA BISQUE.
SEE WHAT'S NEW FROM CAMPBELL'S.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
♪for your information
SEE WHAT'S NEW FROM CAMPBELL'S.
♪we're two of a kind
♪Two of a kind
♪it's my observation
♪we're two of a kind
♪Like peas in a pod
♪and birds of a feather
♪alone or together you'll find
♪that we are two-oo-oo,
oo-oo-oo, oo-oo-oo, of a kind♪
CAPTAIN.
WAIT.
THIS WILL BE THE START
OF THE FORMAL NEGOTIATIONS.
I TOOK THE LIBERTY OF REMOVING
THIS FROM YOUR STATEROOM, SIR.
IT'S THE LAST ONE.
THANK YOU, LIEUTENANT.
NOT EASY BEING THE X.O.,
IS IT?
NO.
IT TAKES TIME TO EARN
THAT KIND OF TRUST.
YES, IT DOES.
SIR.
WHAT ARE YOU HOPING
TO GET OUT OF THIS MEETING?
GOOD TO SEE YOU, C.O.B.
I DIDN'T REALIZE I'D GIVEN YOU
SIX DAYS OFF.
I HAD CREW OUT
LOOKING FOR YOU.
MY APOLOGIES, SIR.
IT COULDN'T BE AVOIDED.
HAD A LITTLE TROUBLE
WITH SOME OF THE LOCALS.
IT TOOK ME A COUPLE OF DAYS
TO SORT IT OUT.
I LOOK FORWARD
TO HEARING ABOUT IT.
LIEUTENANT, BRING THE C.O.B.
UP TO SPEED.
NO NEED, SIR. I, UH, I KNOW
YOU GOT A REPRESENTATIVE
OF THE PEOPLE'S REPUBLIC
UP THERE.
AND, UH, IF HE FLIES
A FLAG ON THAT SHACK,
IT BECOMES CHINESE SOIL.
WHERE YOU BEEN
ALL THIS TIME, C.O.B.?
UH, FORCED WALKABOUT.
CLEARS YOUR MIND.
YOU SHOULD TRY IT.
(knock on door)
(clatter)
AH, CAPTAIN CHAPLIN.
THANK YOU
FOR THE ACCOMMODATIONS.
THEY ARE MORE THAN GENEROUS.
UH, WE'RE STRETCHED A LITTLE
THIN FOR CREATURE COMFORTS,
BUT I HOPE IT'LL SUFFICE.
OH.
THANK YOU.
YOUR MAYOR STOPPED BY
EARLIER AS WELL.
THE TITLE IS SELF-AWARDED.
HE'S A LOCAL THUG
WITH DELUSIONS OF GRANDEUR.
I RECOGNIZE THE SPECIES.
ALLOW ME TO PRESENT
THIS GIFT TO YOU.
THIS WAS
MY GRANDFATHER'S GO BOARD.
DO YOU PLAY?
I'M MORE OF A CHESS MAN.
CHESS.
IN CHESS, THE VICTOR
IS THE ONE WHO ANNIHILATES
HIS OPPONENT'S ARMIES.
IN WEIQI, OR GO,
VICTORY GOES TO THE ONE
WHO CAN CONTROL
THE MOST TERRITORY
WITH THE FEWEST ARMIES.
A BETTER GAME FOR OUR TIMES.
MAYBE.
I'M AWARE OF WHAT I STAND
TO GAIN BY YOUR PRESENCE HERE--
PROTECTION.
ANY COUNTRY THAT ATTACKS US
ATTACKS CHINA.
IT LEGITIMIZES US.
YOU'LL NO LONGER BE AT THE MERCY
OF THE UNITED STATES.
AT THE MERCY OF
THE CURRENT ADMINISTRATION.
DON'T EVER CONFUSE MY NATION
WITH ITS CURRENT RULER.
WELL, ONE CAN ONLY BE
A REFLECTION OF THE OTHER.
IN RETURN, CHINA GARNERS
INTERNATIONAL PRESTIGE.
CHINA LEGITIMIZES
THE ROGUE CAPTAIN
AND BY DOING SO,
ATTACKS U.S. CREDIBILITY.
I BECOME A PUPPET
WITH A NUCLEAR SUBMARINE.
CHINA COULDN'T MAKE YOU
A PUPPET EVEN IF WE WANTED TO.
YOU'RE A POWERFUL SYMBOL
THE WORLD OVER.
A SYMBOL OF WHAT?
MY WIFE AND I
AT HOOVER DAM.
SHE LOVES THE GRAND CANYON,
BUT FOR ME, THIS--
THIS IS STUNNING.
GREAT AND AUDACIOUS,
HUMBLING
IN ITS AMBITION AND HEART.
YOU ARE THAT SYMBOL.
AFTER THE EVENTS OF PAKISTAN
AND YOUR ACTIONS
AGAINST INDIAN IMPERIALISM,
TO THE MANY WHO QUESTION WHERE
THE HEART OF AMERICA LIES,
IT'S FELT.
PERHAPS IT LIES IN YOU.
(footsteps approach)
(Brannan) SIR.
THERE'S A PROBLEM AT THE PRISON.
IT'S HAWKES.
ANOTHER MINUTE, WE'D HAVE BEEN
DIGGING A HOLE FOR YOU.
IS THAT WHAT
YOU REALLY WANT?
SON, I KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
WAS A TERRIBLE THING.
BUT I DON'T WANT TO LOSE
ANY MORE LIVES
THAN I ALREADY HAVE.
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
YOU CAN SURRENDER.
THAT'S IT.
I SINCERELY HOPE
YOU FEEL BETTER.
(door closes)
WHY WASN'T HE
ON SUICIDE WATCH?
WE'VE NEVER CONSIDERED
SUICIDE WATCH.
WE BARELY HAVE ENOUGH PEOPLE
TO GUARD THEM AS IT IS.
WE'RE NOT EQUIPPED FOR THIS.
UH, NO, SIR.
WE NOW HAVE 25 PRISONERS THAT WE
HAVE TO MAINTAIN, AND FRANKLY,
THE ACTIVE CREW IS STARTING TO
RESENT THE PRISON POPULATION.
THESE GUYS DON'T HAVE TO WORK
FOR THEIR RATIONS.
SO THE WAY THEY SEE IT,
THEY'RE GETTING A FREE RIDE.
YOU GETTING ALL THIS, C.O.B.?
YES, SIR.
I LEAVE FOR A WEEK, AND WE
BECOME THE U.S.S. LEAVENWORTH.
A THIRD OF THE CREW THOUGHT
THEY'D BE GOING HOME LAST WEEK,
AND WHEN THAT FELL THROUGH,
THEY STARTED ACTING OUT.
SO, LIEUTENANT,
YOU AND THE C.O.B. FIND A WAY
TO DEAL WITH OUR DISCIPLINARY
PROBLEM. UNDERSTOOD?
YES, SIR.
BRANNAN, WITH ME.
NEED A WORD, C.O.B.
HEY, C.O.B.
I SAID I NEED A WORD.
(grunts)
LISTEN, WHILE YOU'VE
BEEN ON VACATION,
I'VE BEEN DOING THREE JOBS.
I NEED YOU A.J. SQUARED AWAY.
(pants) OH.
WHAT'S WRONG?
I CAN'T LET HIM
SEE ME LIKE THIS.
OHH!
(opens zipper)
(exhales deeply)
(zipper opens)
THAT'S A LOT OF MONEY
RIGHT THERE.
(zippers opening and closing)
THAT WHY YOU CAME
TO MANILA?
I CAME TO HELP YOU,
YOU UNGRATEFUL BASTARD.
(chuckles)
I GOT 'EM ALL OVER--
MANILA, JAKARTA, KABUL.
YOU KNOW,
YOU TAKE DOWN A KINGPIN
WHO'S BEEN RUNNING DRUGS
FOR 30 YEARS...
(clicks)
BEFORE YOU REMAND THE CASH...
HMM. TAKE A LITTLE
FOR YOURSELF.
IT'S NOT STEALING.
IT'S INSURANCE...
IN THE UNLIKELY EVENT
YOU BECOME AN INCONVENIENCE
TO YOUR COUNTRY.
(chuckles)
(closes zipper)
SO YOU THINKING
ABOUT CUTTING OUT
AFTER WE FIND CHRISTINE?
YEAH.
YEAH, I AM.
I'M NOT LIKE YOU AND WES--
YOU KNOW, FAMILY MEN.
(chuckles)
FOR ME, FAMILY WAS, UH,
MOM TAKING THE EMPTIES
OUT THE BACK DOOR
AND DAD TURNING UP THE TV
TO DROWN OUT THE SOUND.
I SIGNED UP FOR THE NAVY
WHEN I WAS 17 ON A FAKE I.D.
A YEAR LATER,
I'M IN THE 46-HOUR HELL WEEK,
MUD CAKED OVER
EVERY INCH OF MY BODY.
I'D JUST FINISHED
A 10-MILE RUN,
AND NOW I GOTTA CARRY A LOG
THE SIZE OF A TELEPHONE POLE
OVER SOFT SAND.
(laughs)
AND I REMEMBER
THINKING TO MYSELF,
MAN...
THIS IS THE BEST FUN
I'VE EVER HAD IN MY LIFE.
NO, I GET IT.
I DO. I GET IT.
THERE'S THIS PLACE
IN BALI...
ROOM SERVICE 24/7,
JACUZZIS ON THE BALCONY,
2 INFINITY POOLS--
ONE 30 FEET ABOVE THE OTHER.
YOU TELL ME,
YOU GET CHRISTINE BACK,
YOU'RE NOT THINKING
ABOUT DITCHING, TOO.
(door opens)
HEY.
HERE YOU GO.
THIS IS THE GUY?
OH, TRUST ME,
IF IT'S IN MANILA AND ON
THE SHADY SIDE OF THE STREET,
HE'LL KNOW WHO'S WALKING THERE.
THANK YOU, BROTHER.
I OWE YOU ONE.
NAH.
(pats shoulder)
HEY, LISTEN, YOU STUCK
YOUR NECK OUT FOR ME.
THANK YOU.
HEY, MY ADVICE?
GET HER OUT
AND DON'T LOOK BACK.
(door opens)
(door closes)
♪
(laughs)
YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE
SPLIT NINES.
WELL, WHAT'S A FEW GRAND
BETWEEN FRIENDS?
I'M STILL FEELING LUCKY.
ACTUALLY...
I'M LOOKING FOR
SOME FOREIGN ACTION.
♪
I DON'T THINK
I CAN HELP YOU WITH THAT.
AMERICAN GAME.
THE EXCLUSIVE KIND.
NO GAME LIKE THAT HERE.
♪
I'M PLAYING A HUNCH.
YOU KNOW WHAT WE CAME HERE FOR.
SO I'M GONNA PUT MONEY
ON THE TABLE.
I'M GONNA PUT
MORE MONEY ON THE TABLE.
AND I'M GONNA KEEP PUTTING MONEY
ON THE TABLE
TILL SOMEBODY NOTICES
AND STARTS TO WONDER
WHAT EXACTLY IT IS
I'M PAYING YOU FOR.
YOU UNDERSTAND ME?
♪
THERE IS AN OLD ABANDONED
WAREHOUSE IN SAMPALOC,
A FEW MILES FROM HERE.
I THINK YOU WILL FIND
A GOOD GAME THERE.
HOW MANY PLAYERS?
FOUR. ALL PILIPINO.
SAVE ONE,
AN AMERICAN NAMED FRANZEN.
BE CAREFUL WITH HIM.
HE CHEATS.
NICE DOING BUSINESS
WITH YOU.
♪
THAT GUY--
HE RECOGNIZE YOU?
I DON'T KNOW. WHY?
YOU KNOW HIM?
LONG TIME AGO.
WE GOT A LOCATION.
WHAT DO YOU WANT TO DO?
(hissing)
(gunfire)
(sniffles)
(panting)
SAM?
SAM. (cries)
NO, I'M OKAY.
LET'S GO.
♪
where'd you get that top?
Sears
You look great.
Thanks.
Where'd you that dress?
Sears
Super Cute.
Where did you get those shoes?
Sears
Excuse me...
Sears everyone!
I got the outfit at Sears!
Surprised? Don't be.
This is great fashion
at great prices.
This is Sears.
Plus save even more
with your savings pass.
[ engine revs ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THE MERCEDES-BENZ WINTER EVENT
IS BACK,
WITH THE PERFECT VEHICLE
THAT'S JUST RIGHT FOR YOU,
NO MATTER WHICH LIST YOU'RE ON.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
C250 FOR $349 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
(sighs)
(rubs hands together)
(exhales)
HEY.
(chuckles)
HI.
ARE YOU OKAY?
(exhales)
THIS IS SO STRANGE.
IT IS STRANGE.
(huffs)
I SAW YOU.
I SAW YOU
ON THE SHIP WITH PAUL.
SAM, NOTHING HAPPENED.
THAT WAS ALL JUST AN ACT.
IT WAS THE ONLY WAY
THAT I COULD GET TO YOU.
THINGS GOT A BIT MORE
COMPLICATED, BUT...
SAM, I LOVE YOU.
ONLY YOU.
EVERYTHING THAT I DID
WAS TO GET TO YOU.
YOU HAVE TO BELIEVE THAT.
OKAY, OKAY, OKAY, OKAY.
I BELIEVE YOU. I BELIEVE YOU.
I BELIEVE YOU.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO SAY
ANYTHING MORE. I BELIEVE YOU.
I LITERALLY DREAMED OF
WHAT THIS MOMENT WOULD BE...
BUT IN MY DREAMS,
YOU'RE WALKING THROUGH
THE FRONT DOOR OF OUR HOME.
I KNOW.
AND WE WEREN'T ON
THE OTHER SIDE OF THE WORLD,
AND IT WASN'T THIS HARD.
HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY, HEY.
COME HERE.
IT'S OKAY.
(kisses) IT'S OKAY.
(whispers) I LOVE YOU.
I LOVE YOU, TOO.
MM.
(groans)
YOU'RE AWAKE.
AS ASTUTE AS EVER,
LIEUTENANT.
YOU TOOK ADVANTAGE OF ME.
I UNDERSTAND.
(chuckles)
WELL, YOU CAN RELY
ON MY DISCRETION.
IT NEVER HAPPENED.
DON'T WORRY.
NO ONE KNOWS
YOU'RE HERE BUT ME.
ARE YOU GONNA TELL
THE CAPTAIN ABOUT THIS?
YOU GONNA TELL ME
WHAT'S GOING ON?
A FEW
OF THE LOCAL BAD GUYS--
THEY JUMPED ME.
THEIR IDEA OF FUN WAS
TO HOG-TIE ME
AND THROW ME IN A DITCH
ON THE OTHER SIDE OF THE ISLAND.
IT TOOK TWO DAYS
WITHOUT FOOD AND WATER
TO WIGGLE OUT.
I'M NOT PROUD.
BUT IF YOU FEEL THE NEED
TO BURDEN THE CAPTAIN,
THAT'S--
THAT'S YOUR PREROGATIVE.
REPORT TOMORROW, 0500.
(exhales)
OH, GOD.
(Zheng) PERHAPS YOUR AMERICA
IS NOT AMERICA ANYMORE.
BUT A RECKONING MAY COME,
AND YOU WILL FIND
THE MEASURES
AND THE COMPROMISES
YOU MAKE
MAY NO LONGER BE TEMPORARY.
I BELIEVE...
IN MY HEART,
THAT ONE DAY I WILL DRIVE
THAT SUB INTO KINGS BAY.
I'LL WALK INTO THE PENTAGON
AND DECLARE,
"I AM CAPTAIN MARCUS CHAPLIN
OF THE U.S.S. 'COLORADO,'
AND I'M HERE
TO CLEAR MY NAME."
I BELIEVE THIS IS TEMPORARY.
AND IF IT ISN'T...
YOU WOULD GO MAD.
(chuckles)
IT'S A TRICKY GAME.
YOU CAUGHT ME.
HERE IS MY OFFER.
I'LL GIVE YOU FOOD,
SUPPLIES,
ANYTHING YOU NEED.
AND IN RETURN?
YOUR JAIL IS FILLED.
YOUR MEN ARE STARVED,
CUT OFF, ATTACKED.
YOU WILL AGREE
BECAUSE WE OFFER THE ONLY
SOLUTION TO YOUR PROBLEM.
AND AS AN ALLY,
WE ARE VERY POWERFUL.
NOTHING IN RETURN.
EVERYTHING IS
IN THE ACCEPTANCE.
I CANNOT ACCEPT.
I WONDER, MARCUS,
WHAT WILL BECOME OF YOU.
(exhales)
I MET THIS KID TODAY.
CHARLIE.
WHAT WAS CHARLIE LIKE?
HE WAS REALLY SMART,
REALLY POLITE,
BUT TOUGH, YOU KNOW?
I MEAN, IF YOU GAVE HIM
A HARD TIME,
HE WOULD BE MORE THAN HAPPY
TO GIVE IT RIGHT BACK TO YOU,
YOU KNOW?
(both laugh)
SAM KENDAL, AGE 9.
YEAH, I GUESS SO.
I MEAN, I HADN'T THOUGHT
ABOUT THAT, BUT, YEAH.
(laughs)
MM.
IF WE HAD A KID,
IT WOULD PROBABLY BE
A LOT LIKE THAT, WOULDN'T HE?
HEY. LOOK AT ME.
WHAT IF WE DISAPPEARED...
RIGHT NOW?
(whispering) JUST DROPPED OFF
THE FACE OFF THE EARTH,
JUST THE TWO OF US.
MAYBE THE THREE OF US.
(whispers)
HOW IS THAT POSSIBLE?
I DON'T KNOW.
(both laugh)
BUT WE WOULD
FIGURE IT OUT TOGETHER.
YOU COULD DO ANYTHING.
YOU COULD PAINT ALL DAY
IF YOU WANTED.
I COULD BUILD SHIPS
FOR MILLIONAIRES.
(laughs)
WE WOULD FIGURE IT OUT.
(sighs)
LOOK, I HAVE BEEN TRYING
TO DO THE RIGHT THING
FOR SO LONG NOW.
TRIED TO BE
THE BEST SAILOR.
THE BEST X.O.
BUT I'M JUST...
I'M TIRED.
LET'S DO IT.
♪
[ chirping ]
[ bleating ]
[ meowing, barking ]
[ Male Announcer ]
UNLIMITED PHONE...
UNLIMITED DATA...
UNLIMITED GIFTS OF JOY.
BUY ONE SAMSUNG GALAXY PHONE...
GET THE SAME MODEL FREE.
VISIT A SPRINT STORE
OR SPRINT.COM/HOLIDAY TODAY.
GET THE SAME MODEL FREE.
For thos...this...ions of doing
this...
...and this,
dancing in their heads...
...we have these.
Home Depot gift cards.
Give the gift of doing,
in-store or online.
BRAVO. BRAV...OH. IS THAT LUNCH?
HOW ABOUT
MOZZAREL-LA-LA-LA-LA-LA-LA.
WENDY'S.
WENDY'S MOZZARELLA
CHICKEN SUPREME.
CRISP CHICKEN, MOZZARELLA,
AND A RICH PARMESAN SAUCE.
NOW THAT'S BETTER.
He is a good little monkey
and always very curious.
One day George got an important
letter...
He's built a rocket ship to
travel into space.
It's just the right size for a
clever monkey.
Do you want to go into space,
George?
You will have to be very brave.
Hi, Grandma!
Oh hi,. my little monkey!
Here.
Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
Everyone got on and they were
off to the launching site.
Google, how far is Earth to the
Moon?
Moon is 238,900 miles...
The great moment had come...
...5...4...3...2...1
I PROPOSE A TRUCE.
I COULD SUPPLY
EVERYTHING YOU NEED.
I KNOW PLENTY OF PIRATES
WILLING TO RISK THE BLOCKADE.
THEY ALREADY HAVE.
IF YOU AND I WERE ON
THE SAME SIDE, CAPTAIN,
JUST THINK OF
WHAT WE COULD ACCOMPLISH.
I GREW UP
WITH MEN LIKE YOU.
CALL THEMSELVES "THE MAYOR,"
ACT LIKE
A FRIEND TO THE PEOPLE,
SAY THEY'LL PROTECT YOU.
(laughs)
SO I DISGUST YOU?
YOU KNOW, I GREW UP
WITH MEN LIKE THAT, TOO.
SO WHY ARE WE DIFFERENT?
BECAUSE YOU BECAME
A SEA CAPTAIN.
YOU THINK YOU ARE NOBLE.
YOU ARE JUST A UNIFORM.
TAKE THAT AWAY, AND YOU
WILL SEE WHAT YOU TRULY ARE.
YOU WANT TO SEE...
WHAT I TRULY AM?
(laughing)
MY OFFER IS STILL GOOD,
CAPTAIN.
GOOD NIGHT.
(car door opens)
(car door closes)
(engine starts)
(knock on door)
ENTER.
YOU NEEDED ME, SIR?
(door closes)
MR. SERRAT SAYS THAT HE WILL
BRING IN ALL MANNER OF PIRATES
AND OUR CUP RUNNETH OVER.
(clatters)
MR. ZHENG OF CHINA
WANTS TO GIVE US AID
AND IS WILLING TO RISK
A CONFRONTATION TO DO SO.
THIS IS WHERE THE, UH,
X.O. USUALLY JUMPS IN
TO PROVIDE ANOTHER PERSPECTIVE,
PROVOKE DEBATE.
UM, SORRY, SIR.
SORRY I'M NOT HIM.
(chuckles) I'VE HAD
TOO MUCH TO DRINK, LIEUTENANT.
YOU CAN STOP
WITH THE BUG EYES.
SO...
YOU'VE BEEN DYING
TO SAY YOUR PIECE.
SAY IT.
THERE ARE ALWAYS
STRINGS ATTACHED
TO ANY OFFER.
AN ALLIANCE, SIR?
WHAT KIND OF MESSAGE
DOES THAT SEND?
HOW DOES THAT HELP
TO GET US HOME?
AND--AND HOW DOES IT HELP
TO CLEAR OUR NAMES WHEN WE DO?
WE'RE NOT A SOVEREIGN NATION,
THEREFORE IT WOULDN'T BE
AN ALLIANCE.
STOP LYING TO YOURSELF.
THIS ADMINISTRATION
WILL STARVE US OUT.
THEY'LL BLEED US DRY.
THEY WILL WATCH MEN AND WOMEN
DIE OF INFECTION
BEFORE THEY MOVE IN.
IS THIS WORTH STARTING
WORLD WAR III OVER?
WORLD WAR III
HAS ALREADY STARTED.
THE BOMBS THAT HIT PAKISTAN
DID MORE THEN DESTROY A NATION.
RESTRAINT IS FAILING.
AND THE QUESTION IS,
LIEUTENANT,
DO WE SKITTER AROUND THE EDGES,
GATHERING CRUMBS,
OR DO WE PLANT OUR FLAG?
I'D LIKE TO HEAR
YOUR POSITION.
I SAID WHAT I BELIEVE.
IT WOULD BE A MISTAKE.
THANK YOU, LIEUTENANT.
(lock clicks, door opens)
(door creaks)
EVERYTHING SET?
WES WILL GIVE US A RIDE
OUT OF TOWN TOMORROW.
GOOD.
I'M HEADED
TO CENTRAL AMERICA.
I'M THINKING COSTA RICA.
YOU MAKE UP YOUR MIND?
I DON'T KNOW.
I HEARD BALI'S NICE.
HEY.
WHAT IS IT?
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
WHAT? WHAT'S WRONG?
THAT GUY FROM THE CASINO?
I MET HIM IN BUD/S.
HE'S A STRANGE GUY,
EVEN BY SEAL STANDARDS.
OKAY.
HE GETS BOUNCED
FROM THE NAVY,
HE GOES INTO BUSINESS
FOR HIMSELF--
MERCENARY WORK.
THAT'S WHAT HE'S DOING
HERE IN MANILA.
KENDAL...
U.S. HAVE PUT
A BOUNTY ON YOUR HEAD.
HOW MUCH?
$5 MILLION.
(sighs)
AND THAT'S THE BIG-TIME,
BROTHER.
I NEVER GOT MORE THAN
A COUPLE HUNDRED GRAND MYSELF.
SAM...
I KNOW THIS GUY.
HE'S VICIOUS.
HE FIGHTS DIRTY
AND HE DOES NOT STOP.
AND IT WOULD BE ONE THING
IF IT WERE JUST HIM,
BUT THERE ARE GONNA BE
A HUNDRED MORE GUYS LIKE HIM
TRYING TO TRACK YOU DOWN
WHEREVER YOU GO.
(sighs)
OKAY.
(exhales deeply)
THAT ONE DADDY!
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
I'M THE WORLD'S GREATEST
DOUGLAS FIR.
I'M THE PERFECT SHAPE,
I'M THE PERFECT COLOR,
MY SCENT?
LIKE MAKING LOVE
TO A LUMBERJACK.
BUT HALFWAY HOME,
MY TWINE GETS LOOSE.
AND YOUR CUT RATE INSURANCE
MIGHT NOT PAY FOR THIS.
SO GET Allstate
WHERE YOU CAN SAVE MONEY
AND BE BETTER PROTECTED
FROM MAYHEM, LIKE ME.
[ Dennis ] MAYHEM IS EVERYWHERE.
SO GET AN Allstate Agent.
ARE YOU IN Good Hands?
I'VE BEEN FORTUNATE TO WIN
ON GOLF'S BIGGEST STAGES.
BUT WHEN JOINT PAIN
AND STIFFNESS
FROM PSORIATIC ARTHRITIS HIT,
EVEN THE SMALLEST THINGS
BECAME DIFFICULT.
I FINALLY UNDERSTOOD WHAT
SERIOUS JOINT PAIN IS LIKE.
I TALKED TO MY RHEUMATOLOGIST
AND HE PRESCRIBED Enbrel.
Enbrel CAN HELP RELIEVE
PAIN, STIFFNESS,
AND STOP JOINT DAMAGE.
BECAUSE Enbrel, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS,
SOMETIMES FATAL EVENTS
INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS,
LYMPHOMA, OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING Enbrel,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START Enbrel IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON Enbrel, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING, OR PALENESS.
[ Phil ]
GET BACK TO THE THINGS
THAT MATTER MOST.
ASK YOUR RHEUMATOLOGIST
IF Enbrel IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
[ Doctor ]
Enbrel, THE NUMBER ONE
BIOLOG MEDICINE
PRESCRIBED BY RHEUMATOLOGISTS.
FOR CENTURIES."
♪
THIS LEVIAN COLLECTION
IS AMAZING.
MAYBE IT'S TIME
TO START YOUR OWN.
[ Female Announcer ]
KAY JEWELERS PRESENTS
TODAY'S LEVIAN COLLECTION...
[ gasps ]
FEATURING EXCLUSIVE
LEVIAN CHOCOLATE DIAMONDS.
FROM THE LEVIAN FAMILY -
WHERE THE LATEST IN FASHION
MEETS FINE JEWELRY.
ONE MORE REASON KAY
IS THE NUMBER-ONE JEWELRY STORE
IN AMERICA.
IT'S...
A WORK OF ART?
♪ EVERY KISS BEGINS WITH KAY
SO ALL OF YOU DO.
YES, FOR SURE.
NOW WHAT'S BETTER?
BEING ABLE TO SHOOT TWO LASERS
OUT OF BOTH OF YOUR EYES
AT THE SAME TIME
OR JUST ONE LASER
OUT OF ONE EYE?
[ all kids ] TWO!
[ Moderator ] OKAY, WHY?
IF IT'S JUST ONE BEAM -- OKAY,
IT DOES A LITTLE BIT OF DAMAGE.
TWO BEAMS -- IT WILL
MAKE SOMETHING EXPLODE!
AND THAT'S MORE FUN?
YEAH!
AND IT'S MORE POWERFUL
YOU'RE SAYING?
YEAH!
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S NOT COMPLICATED.
DOING TWO THINGS AT ONCE
IS BETTER.
AND ONLY AT&T'S NETWORK
LETS YOU TALK AND SURF
ON YOUR IPHONE 5.
♪
(indistinct shouting)
PUT 'EM IN THE BRIG.
(shouting continues)
HEY! STOP. STOP!
(engine turns off)
SEE THAT THESE MEN GET
MEDICAL ATTENTION IMMEDIATELY.
WHERE'S THE C.O.B.?
I--
WHERE IS THE C.O.B.?!
(shouting continues)
LAST I SAW HIM,
HE WAS AT THE PRISON.
SIR, IT SEEMS LIKE
SOME OF THE--
ENOUGH. ENOUGH.
LIEUTENANT SHEPARD,
GO TO THE PRISON.
HAVE ALL THE PRISONERS
DRAW STRAWS. TWO SHORTS.
BRING ALL THE PRISONERS
AND HAVE THE ENTIRE CREW
FALL IN AT 1600.
UNDERSTOOD?
YES, SIR.
OH!
OKAY. (chuckles)
YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE TO STOP DOING THAT.
THAT HASN'T BEEN
ANYWHERE UNSANITARY, HAS IT?
$6 MILLION,
TRANSFERRED TO AN ACCOUNT
IN THE CAYMANS.
HALF TOMORROW,
THE OTHER HALF IN THREE DAYS.
IS MONEY REALLY THE ONLY THING
YOU CARE ABOUT?
WHAT ABOUT YOUR S.E.A.L. TEAM?
WHAT ABOUT THE CREW
OF THE U.S.S. "COLORADO"?
HALF'S FOR ME.
THE OTHER HALF'S FOR JAMES KING
SO WE CAN BOTH BE GHOSTS.
AND YOU'RE AN ODD ONE
TO CAST STONES.
(click)
HALF TOMORROW
AND YOU CAN SEE THE REST.
AND IF YOU THINK
IT'S WORTH THE OTHER HALF,
IT'S ALL YOURS.
FINE. YOU'LL GET IT.
JUST LEAVE ME--
TIME TO GO.
(Robert) KYLIE.
KYLIE, LOOK, I KNOW YOU HAVE
NO REASON TO TRUST ME RIGHT NOW,
BUT YOU HAVE TO LISTEN
TO ME, PLEASE.
WHO'S THIS GUY?
SOMEONE I WOULD LIKE YOU
TO KILL.
SERIOUSLY?
NO. LOOK, YOU JUST PASSED
TWO TRAFFIC C.C.T.V. CAMERAS,
AND THERE'S AN A.T.M.
ACROSS THE ROAD.
IN ABOUT FIVE MINUTES,
THERE'S GONNA--
WOULD YOU JUST SHOOT HIM?
WOULD YOU STOP SAYING THAT
TO SOMEONE WHO'S ACTUALLY
CARRYING A GUN?
PETTY OFFICER HOPPER,
I AM TRYING TO SAVE YOUR LIFE,
BOTH OF YOU.
THERE ARE PEOPLE,
POWERFUL PEOPLE,
WHO ARE GATHERING RIGHT NOW,
ORGANIZING...
A COUP D'ETAT.
NO, THOSE HAPPEN IN
THIRD-WORLD COUNTRIES, NOT HERE.
IT'S GONNA HAPPEN HERE,
AND YOU TWO COULD BE
THE TIPPING POINT.
PLEASE LET ME SHOW YOU.
PLEASE.
OR THIS COULD END
FOR ALL OF US RIGHT NOW.
(whirring)
(brakes squeal)
YOU MUST BE WES.
YEAH.
THANK YOU FOR EVERYTHING.
OH, I DIDN'T DO ANYTHING
ANYBODY ELSE WOULDN'T DO.
I DON'T THINK SO.
WE SHOULD GET GOING.
YEAH.
COME HERE.
(kisses)
LOOK...
NO.
IT WAS JUST
A CRAZY DREAM.
I MANAGED TO GET AHOLD
OF YOUR FRIEND KYLIE.
THERE'LL BE A PRIVATE PLANE
WAITING FOR YOU
AT THE AIRPORT IN SILAY.
WES IS GONNA TAKE YOU
TO THE AIRPORT.
WAIT A MINUTE. I THOUGHT
YOU WERE BOTH GOING.
CHANGE OF PLANS.
YOU'RE GONNA DRIVE HER
TO THE AIRPORT, OKAY?
AND SAM'S GOING BACK
TO THE ISLAND.
IF YOU'RE WITH ME,
YOU'RE NOT SAFE.
I DON'T CARE.
YEAH, I KNOW. I DO.
THE PLANE'S GONNA TAKE YOU
TO GENEVA.
(paper crinkles)
HERE'S THE ADDRESS
OF AN APARTMENT
WE'VE ARRANGED FOR YOU--
LOOK, I'M NOT GOING
TO GENEVA, SAM.
YOU CAN'T GO BACK TO THE STATES,
CAN YOU? CAN YOU?
12 HOURS AND 27 MINUTES--
THAT IS HOW LONG IT TOOK
BETWEEN THE NAVY
KNOCKING ON OUR FRONT DOOR
AND THE PHONE RINGING AND YOUR
VOICE BEING ON THE OTHER LINE.
OKAY? 12 HOURS
OF ME NOT KNOWING
IF YOU WERE DEAD OR ALIVE,
AND ALL THAT I COULD DO
WAS WAIT--SIT AND WAIT.
I CAN'T SIT LIKE THAT, SAM.
OKAY, I KNOW.
I DON'T WANT THAT FOR YOU.
I DON'T.
I WANT YOU TO HAVE A LIFE.
A REAL LIFE WITH
A HUSBAND AND KIDS--A LIFE.
SAM, I HAVE ONE.
NO, YOU DON'T.
I HAVE ONE.
AND I CAN WAIT
FOR THE REST, OKAY?
WE'LL HAVE THAT
WHEN WE CAN BE TOGETHER
WITHOUT HAVING TO LOOK
OVER SHOULDERS--
REALLY,
REALLY TOGETHER.
COME HERE. I LOVE YOU.
OKAY? I LOVE YOU.
YOU BE SAFE.
(tires squealing)
OKAY, LOOK, I DON'T KNOW
WHERE ANYBODY'S GOING,
BUT IT HAS GOTTA BE NOW.
(tires squeal)
GET HER TO THE AIRPORT.
COME ON, CHRISTINE.
GO, GO, GO, GO, GO!
GO, GO, GO, GO!
(gunfire)
LET'S GO.
SAM!
(gunfire continues)
(bullets ricochet)
(bullets thudding)
AAH!
(gunfire continues)
HEY, COVER ME! COVER ME!
(click)
COME ON. LET'S GO!
LET'S GO!
(panting)
(gunfire)
(sirens wailing)
SAM. YOU HEAR THAT?
THOSE COPS
ARE NOT OUR FRIENDS.
WE STAY HERE, WE DIE.
SAM. SAM, SHE'S GONE.
(wailing continues)
WE GOTTA GO.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
COME ON!
(wailing continues)
Intel Mnemonic
♪
You work.
You play.
You type.
You connect.
But the one thing you haven't
done on a notebook,
is touch.
♪
Extend your reach
with the all new
HP Envy 4 TouchSmart Ultrabook
with Intel Core i3 processor.
Only at Best Buy.
TO TELL REAL PEOPLE ABOUT
OUR NEW 15 UNDER $15 MENU.
OH MY GOODNESS!
OH MY GOSH,
THIS LOOKS AMAZING!
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR NEW MAINE STAYS!
15 ENTREES UNDER $15,
SEAFOOD, CHICKEN AND MORE!
OO! THE TILAPIA
WITH ROASTED VEGETABLES!
I'M ACTUALLY LOOKING AT
THE WOOD GRILLED CHICKEN
WITH PORTOBELLO WINE SAUCE.
THAT PORK CHOP
WAS GREAT!
NO MORE
FAST FOOD FRIDAY'S!
WE'RE GOING TO GO
TO RED LOBSTER.
YEP.
[ Male Announcer ]
COME TRY OUR NEW MENU
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY!
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
SALAD, SANDWICHES, AND MORE.
[ GPS ] HELLO DAVE.
OH, NOT AGAIN.
[ GPS ] DAVE, DO YOU KNOW WHERE
YOUR WIFE WENT LAST WEEK?
SHE WENT TO JARED TO LOOK AT
A BEAUTIFUL DIAMOND NECKLACE.
I'M NOT GOING TO
THE CLEANERS ANYMORE, AM I?
[ GPS ] NO DAVE, YOU'RE NOT.
[ wheels screech ]
RIGHT TURN.
[ engine revs ]
[ Male Announcer ]
JARED THE GALLERIA OF JEWELRY
HAS FIVE TIMES THE SELECTION
OF ORDINARY JEWELRY STORES...
SO YOU'LL FIND
THE PERFECT GIFT EVERY TIME.
HOW DID YOU KNOW?
WHO KNOWS YOU LIKE I DO?
[ horn honks ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THAT'S WHY HE WENT TO JARED,
THE GALLERIA OF JEWELRY.
YOU SPEND ALL DAY COOKING IT.
SO WHY SPEND EVEN A MOMENT
CONSIDERING ANY BROTH
BUT SWANSON?
THE BROTH COOKS TRUST MOST
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
IN STUFFING AND MORE,
THE SECRET IS SWANSON.
OK!
IT'S A NEW WAY
TO GET CASH BACK DEALS
AND IT'S CALLED BANKAMERIDEALS.
I SIGN IN
TO MY ONLINE BANKING...
CLICK THE "CASH BACK DEALS"
TAB...
AND PICK THE DEALS I WANT.
I JUST USE MY BANK OF AMERICA
DEBIT OR CREDIT CARD WHEN I PAY.
AND THEN I GET
UP TO 15% CASH BACK...
PUT INTO MY ACCOUNT!
I KNOW, RIGHT?
[ Male Announcer ]
INTRODUCING BANKAMERIDEALS,
FREE FOR
ONLINE BANKING CUSTOMERS.
SIGN IN TO YOUR ONLINE BANKING
TO CHOOSE YOUR DEALS TODAY.
FREE FOR
ONLINE BANKING CUSTOMERS.
Every picture tells a story.
Of course, some stories are
bigger than others.
Okay guys, here we go.
Everybody say,
'cheeeeeeeee-eeeeeese'.
Got it.
FROM THEFT TO ASSAULT
TO DESERTION,
ALL OF YOU
HAVE COMMITTED CRIMES
WHICH HAVE PUT YOUR FELLOW
CREW MEMBERS IN DANGER.
WE NO LONGER HAVE THE RESOURCES
TO FEED YOU, TO HOUSE YOU,
TO GUARD YOU.
IN SHORT, THIS AIN'T WORKING.
PRISON IS A LUXURY
WE CAN NO LONGER AFFORD.
AND LET ME ASSURE YOU,
GENTLEMEN,
JUST AS THERE ARE NO ATHEISTS
IN FOXHOLES,
THERE ARE NO PRISONS
ON THE BATTLEFIELD.
AND AS BEAUTIFUL
AS IT MAY SEEM,
THAT'S WHERE
WE FIND OURSELVES TODAY,
ON THE BATTLEFIELD,
FIGHTING FOR OUR LIVES,
OUR HONOR,
AND I BELIEVE OUR NATION.
LIEUTENANT,
THE PRISONERS DREW STRAWS?
YES, SIR.
WHOEVER DREW THE SHORT STRAWS
WILL BE LASHED.
THE REST OF YOU, TO A MAN,
WILL RETURN TO YOUR DUTY.
THERE ARE NO CRIMINALS
ON SAINTE MARINA,
ONLY CRIMES
AND THEIR PUNISHMENT.
AS OF TODAY, THERE IS NO BRIG
OF THE U.S.S. "COLORADO."
AM I UNDERSTOOD?
(crew) SIR, YES, SIR.
I REGRET THAT IT'S COME
TO THIS.
WHO DREW THE SHORT STRAWS?
WHO DREW
THE SECOND SHORT STRAW?
(Brannan) SIR.
I WAS NEVER PUNISHED
FOR PUTTING THE SUB
AND THE CREW IN DANGER.
I WOULD LIKE TO VOLUNTEER.
MASTER-AT-ARMS,
DISPENSE THE PUNISHMENT.
NO.
I'LL DO IT, SIR.
(lowered voice) I'M THE ONLY ONE
THAT SHOULD DO THIS,
AND YOU KNOW IT.
DO IT RIGHT, JOE.
YES, SIR.
STEP UP, SAILOR.
MASTER-AT-ARMS.
(blood pressure cuff pumping)
(Velcro rips)
(birds chirping)
(under breath) CLEAR OUT, SON.
(rope whooshes)
OUR TWO NATIONS ARE
BEACONS OF THE FIRST WORLD,
YET MILLIONS LANGUISH
IN OUR PRISONS.
YOUR CHOICE TODAY...
WAS PERHAPS
THE MORE HUMANE ONE.
IF I TAKE YOUR ASSISTANCE...
YOU'LL BE POKING
THE UNITED STATES IN THE EYE,
AND THEIR RESPONSE
WILL BE AGGRESSIVE.
IF YOU DO NOT TAKE
OUR ASSISTANCE,
WHO KNOWS WHAT GREATER LENGTHS
YOU WILL HAVE TO GO TO?
TODAY IT WAS LASHINGS.
WHAT MEASURES
MIGHT TOMORROW BRING?
DOES CHINA REALLY CARE
ABOUT ANY OF THAT?
NO.
CHINA DOES NOT.
YOU WILL NOT BE ALLOWED
ABOARD THE "COLORADO," EVER.
YOU WILL HAVE YOUR SUPPLIES
IN 48 HOURS.
AND I'D LIKE TO REMAIN HERE,
WITH YOUR PERMISSION.
YOU HAVE IT.
YOU GOTTA BE KIDDING ME.
(speaking inaudibly)
(sizzling)
YEAH.
THANKS.
(switch clicks)
(sets down dish)
(utensil scrapes dish)
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO EAT,
CHRISTINE.
YOU MAY BE HERE A WHILE.
LOOK, I'M NOT A BAD GUY.
OKAY? I DIDN'T PLAN THIS.
I'M JUST DOING WHAT I HAVE TO
TO TAKE CARE OF MY FAMILY.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
COME ON.
(spoon clinks)
(clinks)
SO HE WILL TELL YOU
HE FEELS FINE.
HE DOES NOT FEEL FINE.
AND IF YOU RELEASE HIM
BEFORE HIS I.N.R. STABILIZES,
HE WILL BLEED TO DEATH.
MURPHY'S GONNA
KEEP AN EYE ON HIM.
(woman)
♪ O'ER THE FIELDS WE GO
I AM GONNA KEEP
AN EYE ON HIM.
(elevator bell dings)
MRS. GELLMAN'S
STILL INTUBATED,
BUT I WANT THE TUBE OUT
BY MONDAY.
HAVE THE NURSES PAGE YOU AS SOON
AS SHE STARTS BREATHING ON HER--
I-I WILL ASK THEM MYSELF.
OH, IT'S NOT TOO MUCH
FOR YOU?
NOT AT ALL.
AND YET, YOU'RE TRYING TO
FOB IT OFF TO PETUNIA HERE,
WITH HER YEARS AND YEARS
OF EXPERIENCE IN CRITICAL CARE.
I WANT YOU TO RELAX
ON YOUR HONEYMOON.
I THOUGHT THAT
YOU'D BE REASSURED
BY HAVING TWO SETS OF EYES
ON YOUR PATIENTS.
THE NOTION OF AN INTERN
HANDLING MY PATIENTS