WAS SCREAMING UNDERSTANDABLY.
BUT WHEN WE SAW THAT AND THEN
SAW THE PICTURES OF THE CHILDREN
BEING BROUGHT OUTSIDE AND
REPORTS THAT THERE WERE TEARS,
THERE WERE SOME CRYING, BUT
THERE WAS NO SCREAMING, THIS WAS
CALM, THE CHILDREN WERE DOING
WHAT THEY HAVE BEEN TOLD TO DO.
THEY ALL LISTENED TO THE
TEACHERS AND THOSE TEACHERS NEED
TO BE COMMENDED AS WE NOW SORT
OF SEE THE SCOPE OF THE TRAGEDY
THAT PLAYED OUT IN THEIR SCHOOL.
THEY WERE TOLD TO GET THEIR
STUDENTS OUT AND TO A NEARBY
FIRE STATION.
I WANT TO BRING IN LIEUTENANT
PAUL VANCE, HE OFFERED THIS
ABOUT WHAT TRANSPIRED.
>> JUST AFTER 9:30 THIS MORNING,
NEWTOWN POLICE RECEIVED A 911
CALL FOR AN EMERGENCY AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
UPON OBTAINING INFORMATION ABOUT
THE STATUS OF THE SITUATION,
REQUESTED ASSISTANCE FROM POLICE
DEPARTMENTS.
ON AND OFF DUTY POLICE RESPONDED
TO THE SCHOOL.
UPON ARRIVAL ENTERED THE SCHOOL
AND BEGAN A COMPLETE, ACTIVE
SHOOTER'S SEARCH OF THE
BUILDING.
CHECKING EVERY DOOR, EVERY
CRACK, EVERY CREVICE OF THAT
SCHOOL.
WE WANTED TO EVACUATE QUICKLY
AND AS EFFICIENTLY STUDENTS AND
TEACHERS INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
THE ENTIRE SCHOOL WAS SEARCHED.
THAT WAS ACCOMPLISHED.
A STAGING AREA WAS SET UP.
STUDENTS AND STAFF WERE PUT IN
THAT STAGING AREA.
THEY WERE REUNITED WITH THEIR
PARENTS AND LOVED ONES.
THERE WERE SEVERAL FATALITIES AT
THE SCENE RIGHT NOW, BOTH
STUDENTS AND STAFF.
THE SHOOTER IS DECEASED INSIDE
THE BUILDING.
A GREAT DEAL OF WORK IS
UNDERTAKEN IMMEDIATELY UPON
LOCATING THE SHOOTER, THERE'S A
GREAT DEAL OF SEARCH WARRANT
ACTIVITY, LAW ENFORCEMENT
ACTIVITY TO ENSURE THAT WE COVER
ALL OF THE BASES TO THAT
SPECIFIC INDIVIDUAL.
SUFFICE IT TO SAY, THE SCENE IS
SECURED.
DANBURY STATE ATTORNEY AND MANY
AGENCIES ARE WORKING TOGETHER TO
ANSWER ALL OF THE QUESTIONS
SURROUNDING EXACTLY WHAT
HAPPENED.
>> THAT WAS THE LIEUTENANT WITH
THE CONNECTICUT POLICE
DEPARTMENT.
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE DESCRIBING
THE SCENE THERE IN EXTRAORDINARY
EFFORT.
ON THE PART OF THE TEACHERS
THERE, THEED A MAIN STRAY OR
THES AND THE AUTHORITIES WHEN
THEY ARRIVED, THEY WENT ROOM BY
ROOM INSIDE THAT SCHOOL AND THEY
SECURED THAT SCENE AS RAPIDLY AS
ANYONE COULD HAVE, CALLED IN AND
NOT KNOWING WHAT THEY WOULD COME
UPON, THEY'RE DEALING NOW WITH A
TRAGEDY OF HOIS OR THEIC NATURE.
THE NUMBERS, SOME OF THE
PICTURES COMING IN FROM OUR ABC
STATION
STATIONS.
THESE OFFICES, AS YOU CAN SEE,
FBI, STATE POLICE THERE, GUN
DRAWNS, GOING CAR TO CAR.
NOT ONLY PARENTS HAVE TO
DESCRIBE WHY CHILDREN LEFT THAT
SCHOOL, WHAT IT WAS SEEING SO
MANY PEOPLE ARMED.
DAN HARRIS DESCRIBED THE
PARENTS.
WHO CAME TO THE SCHOOL AND IN
MANY CASES TAKING OFF THEIR
COATS, WRAPPING THEIR CHILDREN
IN THEIR COATS, BECAUSE THE
CHILDREN WERE SIMPLY TOLD TO GET
OUT, GRAB A BUDDY AND EXIT.
WE SHOULD TELL YOU, THAT MY
COLLEAGUE CAN DIANE SAUER IS ON
THE SCENE, SHE'LL BE
BROADCASTING THERE ON "WORLD
NEWS."
IN THE MEANTIME, SOME OF THE
PARENTS AND WHAT THEY TOLD DIANE
A LIMTTLE EARLIER HERE.
WE'LL BRING THAT TO YOU, AGAIN,
AS SOON AS WE HAVE IT AND WE
HAVE IT NOW.
>> ALL SCHOOLS WERE IN LOCKED
DOWN.
IT DIDN'T SAY WHAT SCHOOL.
THEN A NEIGHBOR SAID THAT THEY
HEARD IT WAS SANDY HOOK.
WHICH IS WHERE OUR CHILDREN GO.
AS A PARENT I KNOW WHOPD TO BE
IN THE BUILDING.
SHE'S PRETTY BROKEN UP.
THEY HEARD SHOOTING.
THEY GOT UP AND WENT OUT.
SHE HAD STAYED IN THE CONFERENCE
ROOM AND MY UNDERSTANDING FROM
HER IS THAT THE PRINCIPAL AND
OTHER PEOPLE GOT SHOT WHEN THEY
WENT OUT INTO THE HALLWAY.
>> I WORKED SO CLOSE, I SAW THE
FIRST COPS ROLLING DOWN THERE.
SO, I JUST LITERALLY RAN DOWN
THERE AND I GOT PRETTY MUCH UP
TO THE SCHOOL WITH A BUNCH OF
OTHER PARENTS RIGHT ON THE SCENE
AND AS THEY WERE LEADING THE
KIDS OUT SINGLE FILE, I SAW HIM
RIGHT AWAY AND JUST WENT WITH
HIM AT THAT POINT.
>> HOW SHAKEN WAS EDWIN?
WHAT DID HE WANT TO TALK TO YOU
ABOUT?
>> HE DOES NOT REALLY WARRANTY
TO TALK ABOUT IT.
HE'S JUST SCARED AND SHAKEN.
HE TOLD US THAT HE DIDN'T SEE
BUT HEARD.
RIGHT NOW, WE'RE JUST FOCUSED ON
COMFORTING HIM.
>> I HEARD THAT CHILDREN WERE
TAKEN OUT BLOODY, SEVERAL
TEACHERS AND A MOTHER WHO WAS
ACTUALLY IN THE SCHOOL SAID THAT
A MASKED MAN CAME IN AND STARTED
FIRING.
>> MY WIFE AND I DROVE RIGHT
OVER THERE AND WE WERE -- WHEN
WE ARRIVED, I WOULD SAY PROBABLY
THERE WERE 30, 40 PARENTS THERE
OR SO, THEY WERE JUST GATHERING
CHILDREN AT THE FIRE HOUSE.
IT BEGAN A CHAOTIC SITUATION.
LIKE I SAID, BETWEEN THE POLICE
AND THE FIRE DEPARTMENT
PERSONNEL THAT WERE THERE AND
ESPECIALLY THE SCHOOL TEACHERS,
I MEAN, I'M JUST SO PROUD OF THE
WAY OUR TOWN HAS RESPONDED TO
THIS.
>> THAT SUMS IT UP FOR THE
PARENTS AND THE PEOPLE ABLE TO
REUNITED WITH THEIR CHILDREN
TODAY.
THAT FATHER SAID IT PERFECTLY,
I'M JUST PROUD OF THE WAY THIS
TOWN HANDLED THIS.
YOU CAN SEE THE HUGS PLAYING OUT
THIS AFTERNOON.
POLICE TAPE DRAWN AROUND THE
SCENE AS AUTHORITIES CONTINUE TO
INVESTIGATE.
I WANT TO BRING IN PIERRE
THOMAS.
BREAKING DEVELOPMENTS INVOLVING
NOT ONLY THE NAME OF THE GUNMAN.
WE KNOW MORE ABOUT WHERE HE'S
FROM AND OTHER DISCOVERIES.
PIERRE?
>> DAVID, WE'RE BEING TOLD BY
MULTIPLE SOURCES THAT THE
SHOOTER HAS BEEN IDENTIFIED BY A
NAME OF RYAN LANZ YA, 24 YEARS
OLD.
WE'RE TOLD HIS MOTHER AT A
TEACHER AT THE SCHOOL IS AMONG
THOSE DECEASED, 24 YEARS OLD.
IDENTIFIED AS THE SHOOTER.
THE RELATIONSHIP AT THE SCHOOL
IS HIS MOTHER.
>> THAT WAS THE SUSPICIOUS SINCE
THE FIRST THING THIS MORNING.
WE HAVE COVERED SO MANY OF THESE
AND YOU JUST A HATE TO HAVE
CONFIRM IT, THE GUNMAN, THE
GUNMAN HAS SOME SORT OF
RELATIONSHIP WITH SOMEONE INSIDE
THE SCHOOL AND THERE YOU HEARD,
PIERRE, REPORTING THAT IT'S RYAN
LANZA, HE'S FROM NEW JERSEY, 24
YEARS OLD.
IT'S BELIEVED HIS MOTHER WAS A
TEACHER IN THE SCHOOL.
IT'S BELIEVED THAT SHE DIDN'T
SURVIVE ALONG WITH 26 OTHERS.
THE TOTAL IS AT LEAST 27 DEAD
AND COUNTING.
MANY OF THEM CHILDREN.
AND AS WE IN THE COMING HOURS
LEARN ABOUT THE FAMILIES WHO
WILL HAVE JUST THE HORRIFIC
JOURNEY AHEAD OF LEARNING
PERHAPS THEIR CHILD DID NOT
SURVIVE.
WE KNOW THAT THE GOVERNOR IS ON
THE SCENE, HE'S MEETING WITH
PARENTS.
A NUMBER OF STUDENTS AND STAFF
MEMBERS DIDN'T MAKE IT OUT OF
THE SCHOOL.
BRAD GARRETT JOINS US, FORGIVE
ME, BRAD, TYPICALLY, WE'RE
TRYING TO GET INTO THE MIND OF
SOMEONE CAPABLE OF SOMETHING
LIKE THIS, THIS IS THE KIND OF
PIECING TOGETHER THAT PROFILERS
LIKE YOU DO IN A CASE LIKE THIS,
4 YEARS OLD AND HIS MOTHER WAS A
TEACHER AT THE SCHOOL.
>> AND SO, WHAT YOU TAKE AWAY
FROM THAT, THERE IS SOMETHING
GOING ON AND PROBABLY LONG TERM
BETWEEN THE TWO OF THEM AND HE
WANTED BEYOND KILLING HER,
OBVIOUSLY, SOMEONE THAT WOULD
COMMIT THIS TYPE OF ACT COULD
HAVE KILLED HIS MOTHER AT ANY
POINT, HE WANTED TO INFLICT
INJURIES AMONG OTHERS BEYOND HIS
MOTHER, PERHAPS WHAT SHE STOOD
FOR IN REFERENCE TO THE SCHOOL,
KEEP IN MIND, PEOPLE WHO DO
THESE THINGS IS DRIVEN BY
DELUSION, THE DELUSION IS, THIS
HAS HARMED ME, THIS WOMAN HAS
HARMED ME, SHE TEACHES THESE
CHILDREN, I'M GOING TO GET RID
OF HER AND THE WORLD AROUND HER.
IT COULD BE THAT.
SOMETHING IN HIS OWN CHILDHOOD
IN RELATION TO HER.
IT'S MY BELIEF WITHOUT KNOWING
ANYTHING ELSE, THIS GOES BEYOND
JUST HER BUT WHAT SHE REPRESENTS
IN ADDITION TO OBVIOUSLY KILLING
HER.
>> BRAD, STICK WITH US.
I WANT TO GO BACK TO PIERRE,
WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT THIS
24-YEAR-OLD AND HIS HOME,
PERHAPS SOME OF THE OTHER AREAS
WHERE HE MIGHT HAVE INFLICTED
PAIN HERE OTHER THAN THIS
SCHOOL?
>> WELL, AGAIN, THIS IS A VERY
FLUID SITUATION.
WE KNOW THAT THERE IS A SEARCH
ONGOING AT A RESIDENCE IN NEW
JERSEY, THOUGHT TO BE THE
RESIDENCE OF HIS PARENTS.
WE'RE TRYING TO GET SOME
ADDITIONAL REPORTING ABOUT WHAT
IS HAPPENING AT THE HOME.
WE'RE NOT QUITE READY TO RELEASE
THAT INFORMATION YET.
UNTIL WE KNOW IT'S ACCURATE.
AGAIN, WHAT MY SOURCES ARE
TELLING ME IS THAT THIS
24-YEAR-OLD RYAN LANZA HAD GONE
ON A SHOOTING SPREE AT MULTIPLE
LOCATIONS AND THAT WE MIGHT
ADDITIONAL DEAD BODIES.
>> CHILLING TO HEAR THAT
DEVELOPMENT.
WE HAVE BEEN FOLLOWING THIS
SHORTLY AFTER 9:30 THIS MORNING.
AS YOU HEARD PIERRE THOMAS, OUR
JUSTICE CORRESPONDENT REPORT
THERE MOMENTS AGO, AUTHORITIES
ARE NOW INVESTIGATING A
4-YEAR-OLD WHOSE NAME IS RYAN
LANZA BELIEVED TO BE FROM NEW
JERSEY.
INVESTIGATORS ARE NOW AT THE
HOME INVESTIGATING WHETHER OR
NOT HE MIGHT HAVE INFLICTED PAIN
ON OTHER PEOPLE.
PIERRE REPORTING THAT IT'S
POSSIBLE THAT THE SCHOOL WASN'T
HIS ONLY TARGET.
WE'LL CHECK BACK IN WITH HIM AS
SOON AS WE GET INFORMATION ON
OTHER POSSIBLE VICTIMS.
WHAT WE DO KNOW THIS AFTERNOON,
THIS WAS A 24-YEAR-OLD, HIS NAME
ON THE SCREEN THERE, RYAN LANZA
OF NEW JERSEY.
HIS MOTHER WAS A TEACHER AT THE
SCHOOL.
SHE WAS ONE OF AT LEAST 27
PEOPLE KILLED INSIDE THAT
SCHOOL, IT'S BELIEVED.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT SHE TAUGHT AT
THE SCHOOL.
I'M GUESSING WE'LL LEARN THAT
QUITE SHORTLY.
THEIR PARTS OF THESE
COMMUNITIES, THE TEACHERS WHO
PROUDLY WHATEVER THEIR SUBJECT
IS, WHATEVER THE GRADE LEVEL IS
IT THEY HAVE BEEN ASSIGNED TO
FOR THE YEAR.
AS YOU LOOK AT THE CALENDAR,
WE'RE HALFWAY THROUGH DECEMBER.
THIS IS TYPICALLY A JOYOUS TIME
IN SCHOOLS, THEY GET THAT BREAK
THEY SO LOOK FORWARD TO, THAT
EXTENDED BREAK THAT TAKE THEM
CHRISTMAS AND NEW YEAR'S
HOLIDAYS.
I'M SURE THAT THE DECORATIONS
THEY HAD, UP AND DOWN THOSE
HALLWAYS, BUT WHAT WE DO KNOW
THAT IT WAS ALL TURNED UPSIDE
DOWN INSIDE THIS SCHOOL, SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
AND JUST LOOK AT THESE IMAGES,
THESE CHILDREN WITH THEIR ARMS
WRAPPED AROUND THEIR PARENTS.
THIS LITTLE BOY WITH HIS HANDS
UP TO HIS FACE.
AND THE TEARS.
SO OFTEN WE HAVE HEARD
THROUGHOUT THE DAY HERE THAT THE
CHILDREN WERE THE ONES WHO WERE
CALMEST, WHO WERE THE MOST
QUIET, THERE WERE TEARS, THERE
WERE CRIES BUT THE MOST -- THE
OLDER PEOPLE, THE PARENTS, THE
OLDER STUDENTS WERE SO WORRIED
ABOUT WHETHER OR NOT THEIR
YOUNGER SIBLINGS WOULD MAKE IT
OUT.
WE HEARD FROM A 17-YEAR-OLD WHO
WAS JUST INCREDIBLY RELIEVED HIS
FOURTH GRADE SISTER HAD MADE IT
OUT.
NOW WILL COME THE DIFFICULT TASK
FOR THE FAMILIES WHO PICKED UP
THOSE KIDS TO EXPLAIN THEM,
THOSE OF US IN THIS INDUSTRY,
HAVE TO ANSWER THE SAME
QUESTIONS EVERY TIME, WHICH IS,
HOW CAN SOMEONE DO THIS?
WERE THERE RED FLAGS?
COULD ANYTHING BE DONE TO
PREVENT THIS TRAGEDY?
HISTORIC IN NATURE.
AS WE KNOW VIRGINIA TECH, AT
THIS POINT, AS WE LOOK BACK, IT
APPEARS THAT VIRGINIA TECH WAS
THE ONLY SHOOTING THE DEADLIER
THAN THE ONE WE'RE REPORTING ON
THIS ONE THIS MORNING.
SOMETHING THAT WE'LL NEVER
FORGET AT VIRGINIA TECH BUT AT
SCHOOLS, ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS,
MIDDLE SCHOOLS ACROSS AMERICA,
WE HAVE NEVER SEEN ANYTHING LIKE
THIS.
THE NUMBERS ARE SIMPLY STOPPING
EVERYONE WHO IS TURNING ON THEIR
TELEVISION OR CERTAINLY ONLINE
TODAY.
AND FOR THOSE OF YOU WHO AREN'T
ABLE TO SIT IN FRONT OF TV, I
CAN ASSURE OUR TEAM AT
ABCNEWS.COM FOLLOWING THIS
MOMENT BY MOMENT AS WELL.
PARTICULARLY FOR THE FAMILIES IN
THAT COMMUNITY WHO ARE WAITING
FOR WORD.
WE WERE TALKING WITH N.J.
BURKETT EARLIER, HE'S MOVED ON
IN REPORTING.
IT'S ABOUT AN HOUR FROM NEW
YORK, NORTHEAST OF NEW YORK
CITY.
HE WAS REPORTING FROM THE
HOSPITAL, WHICH IS DANBURY
HOSPITAL, THAT WAS THE DEDICATED
HOSPITAL FOR THIS INCIDENT.
THE MOMENT THE CALL CAME IN.
YOU CAN SEE THE GEOGRAPHY WE'RE
TALKING ABOUT.
NEWTOWN NOT FAR AWAY FROM NEW
YORK.
IN DANBURY THAT'S WHERE THE
HOSPITAL IS, THEY HAD PREPARED
FOR THIS.
N.J. REPORTING THAT THE NURSES,
THE TEAMS INSIDE THAT HOSPITAL
SHAKEN BUT I'M SURE DETERMINED
TO HELP THE PEOPLE WHO CAME
THROUGH THAT DOOR.
WHAT WAS STUNNING TO HEAR IN
THIS CASE, ONLY THREE PEOPLE
THAT WE KNOW OF SO FAR, BEING
TREATED AT THE HOSPITAL.
SO MANY OF THE AMBULANCES, THOSE
AMBULANCES PULLING UP AND
SITTING THERE.
NO LIGHTS, NO SIRENS AND VERY
FEW OF THEM, IF ANY, LEFT THE
SCENE WITH ANYONE TO BE SAVED.
THAT IS SIMPLY STAGGERING.
THAT THIS IS ONE OF THE THINGS
ABOUT THIS THAT MAKES IT SO
HEINOUS AND SO HARD TO
COMPREHEND, THE PEOPLE WHO
DIDN'T MAKE OUT OF THIS SCHOOL
DIDN'T EVEN HAVE A CHANCE.
AT LEAST 27.
WE KNOW THAT MANY OF THEM ARE
CHILDREN.
AND BRAD GARRETT OUR FBI
PROFILER WHO WE TURN TO IN THESE
CASES TALKING ABOUT HOW PEOPLE
WHO COMMIT THESE KIND OF CRIMES
PARTICULARLY WHEN THEY WALK IN
AND INTO A SCHOOL LIKE THIS, AND
IT'S SO IMPOSSIBLE TO UNDERSTAND
HOW THEY CAN TARGET YOUNG
CHILDREN IN THEIR CLASSROOMS
DOING WHAT IT IS THEY'RE TOLD
TO, HOW THEY COULD DO THIS,
COMMIT THIS WITH CHILDREN WHO
ARE SO INNOCENT AND AS I
MENTIONED A MOMENT AGO, JUST
SHOWING UP TO SCHOOL, KNOWING A
COUPLE OF WEEKS, IF I REMEMBER
CORRECTLY, EVERY ONE OF THOSE
CHILDREN HAD THAT COUNTDOWN IN
THEIR HEAD, HOW MANY DAYS LEFT
NOT ONLY TO CELEBRATE CHRISTMAS
BUT TO TAKE THE HOLIDAY BREAK?
TO CELEBRATE NEW YEAR'S.
TO SEE WHAT WOULD HAVE BEEN
BROUGHT UNDER THE TREE, WE DO
KNOW THAT THE PRESIDENT HAS BEEN
BRIEFED ON THIS REPEATEDLY
THROUGHOUT THE DAY.
JAKE TAPPER IN THE BRIEFING
ROOM.
WE'LL CHECK IN WHEN WE CAN.
WE KNOW THAT THE PRESIDENT
REACHED OUT TO CONNECTICUT
GOVERNOR DAN MALLOY.
HE HAS THE NEARLY IMPOSSIBLE
TASK OF MEETING WITH PARENTS WHO
DO NOT KNOW WHERE THEIR DHICHILN
ARE AND WE DON'T KNOW IF THE
PARENTS OF THE VICTIMS HAVE BEEN
TOLD.
THE FAMILY MEMBERS OF THE
TEACHERS WHO WERE SHOWING UP TO
DO THEIR WORK TODAY AND WON'T BE
COMING HOME AFTER THIS UNFOLDED
TODAY.
WE BELIEVE THAT THE PRESIDENT
WILL BE SPEAKING IN A
HALF-HOUR'S TIME.
WE'LL BE STAYING WITH YOU AND
YOU'LL BE ASSURED THAT WE'LL
BRING YOU THE PRESIDENT AS SOON
AS HE APPEARS BEFORE THE CAMERA.
THE PEOPLE WHO FOLLOW THIS
PRESIDENCY, HE OFTEN TALKED
ABOUT HIS TWO DAUGHTERS AND WHAT
THEY SEE AT SCHOOL WITH THEIR
FRIENDS, AND NO QUESTION THAT
HE'LL APPEAR BEFORE THAT CAMERA
TODAY NOT ONLY AS OUR PRESIDENT
BUT AS A FATHER AS WELL, THE
WHITE HOUSE SPOKESMAN SAYING
THAT THE PRESIDENT IS AFFECTED
AS IN PARENT WOULD BE THINKING
ABOUT HIS OWN CHILDREN.
>>> I WANT TO BE IN DR. JEN
ASHTON, AS WE AWAIT THE
PRESIDENT, WE EXPECT TO HEAR
FROM HIM WITHIN A HALF-HOUR.
HE'S A FATHER, TOO, THERE'S THIS
DELICATE TASK IN THE NEXT HOURS,
DAYS, TO NOT ONLY OVERTALK THIS
BUT TO TALK IT THROUGH WITH YOUR
CHILDREN AND WHAT A TASK IT IS.
>> IT IS AN UNFATHOMABLE TASK,
DAVID.
I DON'T THINK YOU HAVE TO BE A
PARENT TO IMAGINE THAT THIS WILL
IMPACT EVERY PERSON WHO HEARSE
THIS STORY, BECAUSE IT'S REALLY
NOT ABOUT BEING A PARENT, IT'S
NOT ABOUT A BEING TEACHER, IT'S
ABOUT A BEING HUMAN BEING.
THE MENTAL HEALTH ASPECT IS
ENORMOUS.
THE ISSUE OF SHOCK AND TRAUMA TO
THE CHILDREN WERE IMMEDIATELY AT
THE SCENE.
THERE'S THE ISSUE OF SHOCK AND
DRAW MA TO THE TEACHERS, TO THE
FACULTIES, TO THE FIRST
RESPONDERS.
THAT SHOCK WAVE WILL CONTINUE
OUT TO EVERY ONE IN THE COUNTRY
IF NOT THE WORLD WHO HEARSE THIS
STORY.
YOU HAVE TO BE CONCERNED WITH
REACTIVE DEPREX, PTSD, THAT
THOSE ARE FIRST AND FOREMOST,
WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT THE SHOOTER,
THIS IS THE FACE OF MENTAL
ILLNESS.
BY DEFINITION, THIS IS REALLY
WHAT YOU CANNOT COMMIT A CRIME
LIKE THIS WITHOUT AN ELEMENT OF
ACUTE PSYCHOSIS.
I'M HAVING A HARD TIME PUTTING
ALL THESE THOUGHTS INTO WORDS AS
I KNOW SO MANY PEOPLE ARE.
IT'S JUST UNTHINKABLE.
>> YOUR PERSPECTIVE IS SO
WELCOME.
WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT MENTAL
ILLNESS, I HAVE TO ASK THE
QUESTION, IF THAT'S THE CASE
THERE HAD BEEN WARNING SIGNS,
FLAGS ALONG THE WAY, WHAT DO WE
DO AS A COUNTRY TO TRY TO REACH
OUT AND PROVENT THESE THINGS?
MENTAL ILLNESS PREVENTS ITSELF
LONG BEFORE WE GET TO SOMETHING
LIKE THIS.
>> RIGHT.
WE HAD AN OPPORTUNITY, ALL TOO
OFTEN IN THE RECENT PAST, TO
BRING THAT TO THE FOREFRONT OF
PEOPLE'S MINDS, THE DEFINITION
OF ACUTE PSYCHOSIS IS IMPAIRED
REALITY TESTING, NO ONE CAN
COMMIT A CRIME LIKE THIS WHILE
HAVING A NORMAL SENSE OF REALITY
AND IMPACT JUDGMENT.
WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT ACUTE BEING
MENTAL ILLNESS ISSUE TO THE
FOREFRONT IT'S --
>> OBVIOUSLY CELL PHONES GETTING
THE BEST OF US, DR. JEN ASHTON
PART OF OUR MEDICAL TEAM.
WE'RE WORKING ON AN HOUR FOR
"WORLD NEWS."
DIANE SAWYER WILL BE REPORTING.
SHE'S TALKED TO MANY OF THE
PARENTS THERE ALREADY.
WE HEARD FOR THOSE PARENTS THIS
MORNING.
"NIGHTLINE" TONIGHT WILL BE ON
THIS.
ABCNEWS.COM THROUGHOUT THE DAY.
THE MEDICAL TEAM HAS BEEN
WORKING WORK
ING NONSTOP.
DR. RICHARD BESSER, YOUR
REPORTING IS FORMED BY BEING A
PARENT AS WELL.
YOU'LL WANT TO GET YOUR CHILDREN
AWAY FROM THE SELL VISION SET.
WHAT DO YOU TELL YOUR CHILDREN,
EVEN IF YOU DON'T LIVE IN THAT
COMMUNITY, AS WE KNOW IN THE AGE
OF INTERNET, TWITTER AND EL
EVERYTHING ELSE, IT WILL BE
ALMOST INESCAPABLE.
>> YOU'RE RIGHT, DAVID, YOU
CAN'T SHIELD OLDER CHILDREN
FROM.
I RECEIVED A TEXT FROM MY HIGH
SCHOOL SON THIS AFTERNOON,
SAYING DAD, WHAT'S THE STORY IN
CONNECTICUT?
THIS IS ABSOLUTELY HORRIBLE.
SO, YOU NEED TO ENGAGE YOUR
CHILDREN, YOU NEED TO KNOW YOUR
CHILD AND KNOW HOW THEY RESPOND
TO STRESS.
AS JEN ASHTON WAS SAYING, WE
HAVE SEEN FAR TOO MANY OF THESE
EVENTS YOU MAY HAVE SOME
UNDERSTANDING OF HOW YOUR CHILD
IS GOING TO RESPOND TO SOMETHING
THAT'S SO DIFFICULT TO
UNDERSTAND.
AND HOW YOU ADDRESS YOUR CHILD,
HOW YOU EXPRESS YOURSELF WILL
REALLY, AGAIN -- YOU WANT TO
PROTECT YOUR OWN FEARS ON THE
SITUATION.
GIVEN YOUR CHILD --
>> WE'LL CHECK BACK IN WITH
RICH, ALL OF OUR TEAM CALLING IN
AS DEDICATED AS THEY ARE, BUT,
YOU KNOW, OFTEN THE BEST OF
THOSE CELL PHONES AS WE'RE
MOVING EITHER TO THE SCENE OR
TRYING TO GET INTO THE NEWSROOM
GET THE BEST OF US.
ZBLMPBL WE'LL CHECK BACK IN WITH
DR. BESSER AND DR. ASHTON AS THE
AFTERNOON DEVELOPS HERE.
IT'S NOW CLOSING IN ON 3:00 THIS
AFTERNOON.
WE HAVE LEARNED FROM THE WHITE
HOUSE THAT PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL
MAKE A STATEMENT TODAY.
HE WAS INFORMED THIS MORNING.
HE'S BEEN BRIEFED SEVERAL TIMES
THROUGHOUT THE MORNING.
HE'LL ADDRESS THE NATION ON
PERHAPS THE WORST SCHOOL
SHOOTING IN AMERICAN HISTORY FOR
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL THAT IS OUR
BELIEF THIS AFTERNOON AND AS WE
KNOW HE'S JUST BEGUN WHAT WILL
BE A SECOND TERM, HE'S NOT BEEN
INAUGURATED BUT THE ELECTION
BEHIND HIM AND THESE ARE THE
THINGS THAT PRESIDENT HAS TO GET
IN FRONT OF THE CAMERA AND
REASSURE THE NATION THAT WE'LL
DO EVERYTHING WE CAN TO MAKE
SURE WE MINIMIZE THE POTENTIAL
FOR THIS TO HAPPEN AGAIN.
YOU CAN SEE THE WOMAN RIGHT
THERE, THE ANGUISH TO HER FACE,
HOLDING A CELL PHONE TO HER EAR,
THAT LITTLE GIRL IN HER PIG
TAILS.
IT'S SOMETHING THAT WE DON'T
EXPECT ON A FRIDAY MORNING,
CLOSING IN ON THE CHRISTMAS, THE
HOLIDAY SEASON IN SCHOOLS ACROSS
AMERICA, WHEN SCHOOL CHILDREN
THINK THEY'RE ALMOST THERE,
THEY'RE ALMOST TO THAT PRIZED
VACATION THAT THEY HAVE EARNED
AND THAT VISIT PERHAPS FROM
SANTA OR IF THEY'RE CELEBRATING
OTHER HOLIDAYS THIS TIME OF
YEAR, THIS ISN'T ANYTHING THAT
WE WANT TO WISH ON ANY SCHOOL OR
ANY LITTLE PERSON IN THIS
COUNTRY.
IS WHAT THEY HAD TO GO THROUGH
TODAY.
>>> I WANT TO BRING YOU UP TO
DATE ON WHAT WE KNOW.
THE GUNMAN HAS BEEN EYE DPENT
MIED AS 24-YEAR-OLD RYAN LANZA.
IT'S BELIEVED THAT HIS MOTHER
WAS A TEACHER AT THE SCHOOL.
WE LEARNED NOT ONLY, A MOTHER
AND A SON.
WE BELIEVE THAT THE MOTHER DID
NOT MAKE IT OUT.
THAT SHE WAS A TEACHER THERE.
WE DON'T KNOW WHAT SHE TAUGHT AT
THE SCHOOL.
I'M SURE WE'LL LEARN THAT AS THE
HOURS UNFOLD HERE.
PIERRE THOMAS REPORTING IN FROM
OUR WASHINGTON BUREAU THAT THE
INVESTIGATION EXTENDS BEYOND
THIS SCHOOL, ALSO A SCENE BEING
INVESTIGATED IN NEW JERSEY,
BELIEVED TO BE THE HOME OR A
HOME RELATED TO THIS FAMILY,
WHERE PERHAPS, THIS 24-YEAR-OLD
INFLICTED EVERYBODY MORE HARM.
PIERRE, NOT READY TO REPORT
ANYTHING BEYOND THAT.
IT'S BELIEVED THAT AUTHORITIES
ARE NOT CONVINCED THAT THIS
SCHOOL WAS THE ONLY PLACE WHERE
THIS 24-YEAR-OLD POLICE BELIEVE
I
INFLICTED SUCH INCREDIBLE HOUR
>> Reporter:.
WE KNOW FROM THE SCENE A FIRST
GRADE TEACHER THE KIND OF
HEROISM THAT WE ALWAYS REPORT,
IT'S BEEN STUNNING HOW QUICKLY
THAT WE HAVE LEARNED IN THIS
CASE, OF THE STORIES OF THE
BRAVERY OF THESE TEACHERS, A
FIRST GRADE TEACHER LOCKING IN
HER KIDS IN A BATHROOM, SHE SAID
THAT THE KIDS WERE BEING SO
GOOD, THEY SIMPLY CAN WE ASK IS
ANYONE OUT THERE?
THEY WERE WORRIED ABOUT OTHERS.
I'M READING THIS QUOTE RIGHT NOW
THAT HAS BEEN HANDED TO ME,
TELLING THEIR FIRST GRADE, I
JUST WANT CHRISTMAS, I DON'T
WANT DIE, I JUST WANT TO HAVE
CHRISTMAS.
THE TEACHER SAID, SHE REPLIED TO
THEM, YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
CHRISTMAS, SHE SIMPLY TRIED TO
BE POSITIVE.
THAT'S THE EXTRAORDINARY TALE OF
JUST ONE TEACHER.
WE APPLAUD ALL OF THEM WHO
CAUGHT THOSE CHILDREN OUT OF THE
SCHOOL.
GRAB A FRIEND, LET'S GET OUT.
THE SINGLE-FILE LINES THAT YOU
SAW, AND LOOK AT THIS IMAGE, SO
MANY AUTHORITIES, THEIR GUNS
DRAWN, WE KEEP COMING BACK TO
THIS MOTHER, THAT SUMS IT UP.
CELL PHONE TO HER EAR, AGONY.
WE KNOW THAT AT 3:30 THIS
AFTERNOON, IT'S JUST BEFORE
3:EASTERN TIME, AT 3:30 WE'RE
EXPECTING TO HEAR FROM DAN
MALLOY, HE'S THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT.
HE HAD THE IMPAOSSIBLE TASK OF
SHOWING UP AT THAT SCHOOL AND
MEETING WITH PARENTS WHO DID NOT
KNOW IF THEIR CHILDREN HAD
SURVIVED IT.
THE FEAR AND THE REALITY OF THIS
IS GOING TO BE SOMETHING THAT
WE'LL BE REPORTING ON, AND
SOMETHING, YOU KNOW, WE WOULDN'T
WISH ON ANY PARENT GOING TO THAT
SCHOOL.
WE HEARD FROM AUTHORITIES ONE
TIME TODAY.
WHO CAME TO THE CAMERAS TRYING
TO REASSURE THAT COMMUNITY AND
THE COUNTRY NOW TUNING IN TO
WATCH THIS.
AUTHORITIES ARRIVED AT THE
SCENE, THEY GOT CALLS, 9:30
MORNING.
THEY WERE THERE A SHORT TIME
LATER.
THEY SEARCHED EVERY CLASSROOM.
WENT DOWN THE HALLWAYS.
TRYING TO MAKE SURE THAT THE
SCHOOL WAS SECURED.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT THE PICTURES OF
THE TEACHERS BRINGING THE
CHILDREN OUT, THEY DIDN'T KNOW
WHETHER THE SCHOOL HAD BEEN
SECURED.
THE STORY OF THAT FIRST GRADE
TEACHER LOCKING HER KIDS IN THE
BATHROOM.
THE ROLE SHE PLAYED IN KEEPING
THEM CALM AND GETTING THEM OUT.
DAN HARRIS HAS BEEN ON THE SCENE
ALL MORNING LONG.
HE WAS AT THE FIRE HOUSE, THE
TRIAGE POINT AND THIS STRUCK ME
EARLIER, IT SORT OF A SIGN OF
TIMES,S THE TECHNOLOGY THAT CAN
HELP US, THERE WERE THESE
REVERSE ALERTS THAT WAS TEXTED
OUT TO PARENTS TO GO TO THAT
COMMUNITY TO FIND THEIR
CHILDREN.
AT FIRST, THE TEXT DIDN'T MAKE
IT COMPLETELY CLEAR WHICH SCHOOL
WAS INVOLVED.
YOU CAN ONLY IMAGINE HOW THIS
SORT OF SPREAD LIKE A SHOCK WAVE
THROUGHOUT THIS COMMUNITY.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
YOU KNOW, SPEAKING TO PARENTS
WHO GOT THAT TEXT.
THERE HAS BEEN A SHOOTING.
YOU NEED TO COME PICK UP YOUR
CHILD.
DIDN'T SAY WHICH SCHOOL.
LOT OF PARENTS, IMMEDIATELY
ASSUMED IT WAS THE HIGH SCHOOL.
A TEXT CAME IN.
JUST A HORRIFYING MOMENT.
WE DON'T EXPECT SCHOOL SHOOTING
TO TAKE PLACE ANYWHERE.
BUT OF ALL PLACINGS, REALLY THIS
PLACE, NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, IS
REALLY TRULY A SURPRISING PLACE
FOR THIS TO HAPPEN.
THIS IS SMALL TOWN, LESS THAN
30,000 PEOPLE, SOUTHERN NEW
ENGLAND, BEAUTIFUL, BEAUTIFUL
PLACE THIS IS A PLACE WHERE THE
TOWN SYMBOL IS A ROOSTER, A
PLACE THAT A REVOLUTIONARY
WORLD, A PLACE WHERE GAME
SCRABBLE WAS INVENTED.
DAVID?
>> DAN, STICK WITH US HERE.
WE'LL CHECK IN WITH SOME OF THE
PEOPLE THAT TALKED TO ON THE
SCENE.
FOR THE VIEWERS WHO HAVE TUNED
THROUGHOUT THE AFTERNOON, WE'RE
JUST SHY OF 3:00 EASTERN TIME,
WE WANT TO RECAP THIS UNFOLDING
SITUATION AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
IT WAS A 911 CALL THAT ALERTED
US ALL THAT SOMETHING HAD GONE
TERRIBLY WRONG AT THIS SCHOOL.
THE SHOOTER HAS BEEN IDENTIFIED
AS RYAN LANZA, IT'S BELIEVED
HUSBAND MOTHER WAS AMONG THE
VICTIMS.
SHE'S A TEACHER AT SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL.
THE SHOOTER IS DECEASED INSIDE
THIS SCHOOL.
AUTHORITIES HAVE BEEN CALLED TO
THE SCENE IMMEDIATELY.
HE WAS WEARING A VEST THAT HE
WAS ARMED, RIGHT NOW WE BELIEVE
THAT HE HAD FOUR WEAPONS, THERE
WA O