HELLO, AMERICA, AND WELCOME
TO "DECK THE BALLS,"
THE SPECIAL CHRISTMAS EDITION
OF "WINTER WIPEOUT."
I'M JOHN ANDERSON, HERE WITH
THE VERY FESTIVE JOHN HENSON.
I LOVES ME SOME CHRISTMAS,
JOHNNY.
GIVES ME A CHANCE
TO SHOW OFF
MY VAST COLLECTION
OF CHRISTMAS SWEATERS...
LOVELY.
BUT LET'S NOT FORGET
WHAT CHRISTMAS IS ALL ABOUT.
YEAH.
GETTING.
YOU MEANT GIVING.
'COURSE. I CAN'T GET
IF YOU DON'T GIVE. GET IT?
I THINK SO.
GOOD.
NOW GIVE ME SOMETHING.
WELL, HOW ABOUT
THE GIFT OF "WIPEOUT"?
I HAVE 24 MEN AND WOMEN
READY FOR THEIR SHOT
AT A $50,000 STOCKING STUFFER,
AND IT ALL BEGINS
WITH THE CHALLENGE OF OUR
ALL-NEW CHRISTMAS QUALIFIER.
FIRST UP,
THE SWEET NUTCRACKER.
AWESOME. OUR SHOW HAS
SOME PRETTY BIG NUTS.
THEN IT'S ON
TO THE CANDY CANES.
CANDY THAT'LL STICK
TO THE ROOF OF YOUR HEAD.
NEXT, IT'S THE JINGLE BALLS,
WITH A CHRISTMAS BONUS, JOHNNY.
GRAB THAT PRESENT
ON THE FOURTH BALL, WIN $500.
(cash register bell dings)
THAT'S A LOT
OF CHRISTMAS HAM.
HO, HO, HO, HO!
AND IT WOULDN'T BE THE HOLIDAYS
WITHOUT SANTA.
HE'LL BE ACTING
AS OUR MOTIVATOR TODAY.
DON'T YOU MEAN
"HO-HO-HO-TIVATOR"?
HE'LL BE USING
THAT SANTA STRENGTH
TO BRING WIPEOUTS TO ALL
THE GOOD LITTLE GIRLS AND BOYS.
FROM THERE,
IT'S UP TO THE SNOWFALL.
THAT'S A BIG FLAKE,
WHICH IS WHAT
MY GUIDANCE COUNSELOR CALLED ME
WHEN HE RECOMMENDED
TRADE SCHOOL.
AND FINALLY,
SANTA'S WORKSHOP.
GUARDED BY
VICIOUS ATTACK ELVES,
HOPPED UP
ON BALLSY'S EGGNOG.
I GOTTA GET
THAT SECRET RECIPE.
MM.
OF OUR 24 HOLIDAY HOPEFULS,
ONLY 12 WILL MOVE ON
FOR A CHANCE AT PUTTING 50 GRAND
UNDER THE TREE, JOHN.
I'M AS EXCITED AS...
ME ON CHRISTMAS MORNING.
WELL, HANG ON
TO YOUR SWEATER, THEN,
BECAUSE I HAVE
ONE MORE PRESENT FOR YOU.
OOH, OOH, OOH!
UH, A KNIT CAP, SKINNY JEANS,
AND A PASHMINA?
NO.
IT IS THE GIFT OF
OUR NEW COHOST, VANESSA LACHEY.
SANTA BROUGHT US A LADY?
THAT'S BEEN ON MY LIST
SINCE '87.
HEY, THANKS, GUYS, SO MUCH.
I JUST WANT TO SAY
I'M A HUGE FAN OF BOTH OF YOU.
ANDERSON,
I LOVE YOUR WORK ON ESPN,
AND, HENSON, YOUR DAD
INVENTED THE MUPPETS, RIGHT?
UH, NO.
OH, WELL, UH... YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'M SURE YOU'VE GOT
OTHER COOL STUFF GOING ON.
IT'S--IT'S COOL.
YEAH, I'M--I'M TAKING A HIP-HOP
DANCE CLASS ON SATURDAYS...
THAT'S GOOD.
IF YOU WANT TO COME DOWN,
CHECK IT OUT.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
MAYBE ANOTHER TIME.
OKAY.
'CAUSE RIGHT NOW
IT'S TIME TO KICK OFF
OUR "DECK THE BALLS"
CHRISTMAS SPECIAL.
HERE'S OUR FIRST CONTESTANT,
JESSICA KERR.
AW, A CHRISTMAS PENGUIN.
AAH!
WHOA. I THINK SHE GOT
INTO MR. PENGUIN'S POPPERS.
WHOO!
YEAH, JESSICA'S OBSESSED
WITH PENGUINS.
I DON'T BELIEVE IT.
VANESSA?
AAH!
OH, MY GOSH.
(John H.) OKAY, I BELIEVE IT.
SHE'S GOT THE OUTFIT, THE DANCE.
I JUST DIDN'T KNOW
PENGUINS SCREAMED.
AAH!
(John A.) MAYBE SHE WAS
RAISED BY PTERODACTYLS.
(air horn blows)
JESSICA THE PENGUIN
FIRST TO TEST
THE SWEET NUTCRACKER.
HOPE SHE LEFT HER NUTS
IN HER OTHER PENGUIN SUIT.
SHE EASES RIGHT PAST
THAT FIRST ONE.
MAYBE THESE GUYS
ARE SWEETER THAN THEY LOOK.
OHH, HO HO, NO!
OH, GOODNESS!
PENGUIN DOWN!
I THINK I'M GONNA
LOVE THE NUTCRACKER.
I CAN FEEL IT
RIGHT DOWN IN MY--
CAREFUL.
BONES! I WAS GONNA
SAY "BONES." JEEZ.
JESSICA THE PENGUIN
ON TO THE CANDY CANES.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA GET ME,
YOU CANDY CANES!
PENGUINS AND CANDY CANES,
OR AS POLAR BEARS KNOW IT,
CHRISTMAS DINNER.
OHH!
OH, HO HO!
THAT IS "OW" CANDY.
OOH, HO HO!
WOW, I HAVEN'T SEEN
A CANING LIKE THAT
SINCE I JAYWALKED
IN SINGAPORE.
BIG FUN NOW FOR PENGUIN--
THE JINGLE BALLS,
FEATURING OUR HO-HO-HO-TIVATOR.
HE WAS GREAT AS TIM ALLEN,
JOHNNY.
HOLY JINGLE BALLS.
YOU SAID IT, SISTER.
MAYBE SHE CAN
JINGLE ALL THE WAY--
OHH!
OH! OH, HO!
OH, HO HO, PENGUINS ARE
SO CUTE AND BOUNCY.
WHOA! AAH!
SOMEBODY SHOULD MAKE
A MOVIE ABOUT THEM.
FIRST LOOK AT THE SNOWFALL NOW,
WHERE JESSICA WILL SWOOP DOWN
PAST THE SPOKES
OF OUR SPINNING SNOWFLAKE.
OHH! SNOW SHE DIDN'T!
OUR FLIGHTLESS BIRD DIDN'T STAND
A CHANCE WITH THE SNOWFALL.
SEA LIONS AREN'T LOOKING SO MEAN
AFTER ALL NOW, ARE THEY?
PENGUIN JESSICA
WADDLING HER WAY OVER
TO THE FINAL OBSTACLE
OF THE DAY, SANTA'S WORKSHOP.
OH, BOY. THERE ARE THE ELVES.
IS ANYBODY ELSE TERRIFIED?
OH!
OH! JUST ME?
BRACE YOURSELF, JESSICA.
OOH!
AH!
PENGUIN JESSICA BATTLING
THROUGH THE AERIAL ELF ATTACK.
OHH!
EE!
INTO BALLSY'S EGGNOG.
YOU EVER SEEN A PENGUIN
DUNKED IN EGGNOG?
I WAS IN A FRATERNITY,
VANESSA.
OH, HO!
OH, HO. DON'T TOY
WITH THESE TOY MAKERS.
YOU DON'T GET TO BE
AN ATTACK ELF
BY BEING A NICE GUY.
COME ON, GIRL.
YOU'RE ALMOST THERE.
(blows raspberry)
OH, HO!
HOPE HER MATE
WASN'T WATCHING.
DON'T WORRY. IT'S WINTER.
HE'S PROBABLY SITTING
ON A GLACIER, INCUBATING AN EGG.
WELL, THIS MARCH OF THE PENGUIN
ENDS WITH A TIME OF 4:39.
I MADE IT! I MADE IT.
WHO'S NEXT?
WELL, BACK AT THE BIG BALLS
IS 34-YEAR-OLD CHRISSA ROBBY,
FROM SALEM, OREGON.
SALEM? SANTA!
IT'S A CHRISTMAS WITCH!
QUICK! SEE IF SHE FLOATS!
YEAH, SALEM, OREGON,
NOT MASSACHUSETTS.
I THINK EVERY WOMAN HAS
A LITTLE BIT OF WITCH IN THEM.
SEE? VANESSA KNOWS
WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
GUYS, THERE IS NO SUCH THING
AS A CHRISTMAS WITCH.
TRUST ME, JOHN.
EVEN SANTA HAS A FEW ENEMIES.
AH, HA HA HA!
OH, HO HO!
OH, THE SNOWFALL KNOWS
HOW TO FLIP A WITCH.
IT TAKES A WICCAN...
MM.
OHH!
AND KEEPS ON TICKIN'.
ALL RIGHT, ENOUGH
OF THIS CHRISTMAS FEAR.
GIVE ME
SOME CHRISTMAS CHEER.
(humming "Jingle Bells")
DONE. MEET WISCONSIN NATIVE
CAREY CONLEY.
OH, MAN. I WISH I COULD
GET THIS AS A RINGTONE.
OH, THAT'S IT.
YEAH, BACK THAT THING UP.
(stops humming)
(applause)
WELL, CAREY CALLS HER IMPRESSIVE
INSTRUMENT THE HUMAN KAZOO,
JOHNNY, AND SHE GAVE VANESSA
A QUICK MUSIC LESSON.
YOU HAVE TO TAKE YOUR LIP
AND PUT IT UNDERNEATH YOUR TEETH
JUST LIGHTLY...
OKAY.
AND THEN HUM.
SO THEN THE VIBRATION--
(hums)
YOU'RE PRETTY CLOSE.
MOM, DAD! DID YOU KNOW
I COULD DO THAT?
(both humming
"We Wish You a Merry Christmas")
I CAN KAZOO!
(laughs)
I'M A HUMAN KAZOO!
I COULD QUIT!
(John H.) WAIT, WHAT?
I COULD GO
TOUR THE COUNTRY.
ABSOLUTELY.
(John H.)
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
YOU CAN'T QUIT
ON YOUR FIRST DAY.
(Vanessa)
THIS IS GREAT.
CAREY, IT'S SO NICE
TO MEET YOU...
(John H.) REALLY?
WE JUST BECAME BESTIES.
AND GOOD LUCK ON THE COURSE.
THANK YOU.
I WAS ABOUT TO BREAK UP WITH
ANDERSON TO MAKE ROOM FOR YOU.
(hums "We Wish You
a Merry Christmas")
(John A.)
WELL, THAT IS PRETTY GOOD.
TAKE THAT. MNH!
ALL RIGHT, MICK JAGGER.
TIME TO GET BACK TO WORK.
OH, YES.
(air horn blows)
ALL RIGHT, MR. NUTCRACKER.
YOU AND ME.
THAT'S RIGHT, HUMAN KAZOO CAREY.
YOU TELL HIM.
I WONDER IF SHE'LL BLOW IT
ON THE SWEET NUTCRACKER.
YEAH? SEE WHAT I DID THERE?
"BLOW IT"? BECAUSE--
YOU'RE A PRO.
(hums, yells)
OH, SHE'S NOT GONNA BE ABLE
TO KAZOO RIGHT FOR A WEEK.
THE NUTCRACKER
IS WHOLESOME HOLIDAY FUN.
CAN WE SEE MORE, PLEASE?
AAH!
OHH, THAT HURTS ME
IN MY SUGARPLUMS.
AH, HA!
OH, HO HO HO!
OH, THEY'VE BEEN MAKING
BEAUTIFUL NUT MUSIC ALL DAY.
OOH!
AHH!
IT'S A CHRISTMAS SPECTACULAR
OF WIPEOUTS.
NUTCRACKERS
WILL MAKE YOU CRY,
AND THEN
THEY'LL LAUGH AT YOU.
NOTHING IS BETTER
THAN CULTURE MIXED WITH...
OHH!
AH, HA--VIOLENCE.
OOF!
OHH!
RIGHT IN THE TUTU.
HO HO HO!
CHEST HAIR, DON'T FAIL ME NOW!
CHEST HAIR?
UHH!
OH! THAT IS
MICHAEL ANGELO GONZALEZ,
AND AS THE NAME SUGGESTS,
HE'S AN ARTIST.
WHAT'S CHEST HAIR
GOT TO DO WITH IT?
EVERYTHING, JOHN.
(Vanessa)
THAT IS FANTASTIC.
HOW DID YOU GET INTO
SHAVING YOUR CHEST?
NO, IT'S, UH,
JUST SOMETHING TO DO.
YOU HAVE CHEST HAIR, YOU MIGHT
AS WELL, YOU KNOW, DESIGN ON IT.
YOU HAVE A CANVAS, USE IT.
(John H.) AMEN, BROTHER,
BUT "WIPEOUT" IS REALLY
MORE OF A PERFORMANCE ART.
WHOO!
AHH!
OH, HO! RIGHT IN
THE GUGGEN-HEINIE.
SNOWFLAKES AREN'T
SUPPOSED TO HURT.
OH, VANESSA.
YOU HAVE SO MUCH TO LEARN.
SO LET'S NOT WASTE TIME.
BACK TO THE START.
'TIS THE SEASON
TO BE BALLSY!
WHOO-HOO!
WHOO-HOO! PAR-TAY!
SOUNDS LIKE SOMEBODY'S
ALREADY BEEN DIPPING
INTO THE HOLIDAY SPIRITS.
THAT'S AMANDA CIURDAR,
AND SHE GAVE VANESSA
THE REAL STORY.
SO WHAT IS YOUR FAVORITE THING
ABOUT CHRISTMAS?
OH, GOSH. I LOVE EGGNOG.
IT'S MY FAVORITE.
(John H.) WHAT-WHAT!
LET'S GET BLITZED!
DO YOU EVER SPIKE
YOUR EGGNOG?
(laughs) SHH.
(John H.)
DON'T BE ASHAMED, SISTER.
WITHOUT BOOZE,
IT'S JUST EGG JUICE AND NUTMEG.
WHAT'S A GUY GOT TO DO TO GET
BALLSY'S SECRET RECIPE, ANYWAY?
(air horn blows)
AMANDA OFF LIKE A SHOT
OF EGGNOG AND HOLIDAY CHEER.
YEAH, THAT'S WHAT SANTA
FEEDS HIS REINDEER,
ESPECIALLY BLITZEN.
WHOA!
WHOA, HO! GIDDYAP!
OH, HO!
AT THE TOP OF THE STEPS,
THERE AROSE QUITE A CLATTER,
BECAUSE BLITZEN GOT HIT
BY A NUTCRACKER BATTER.
BLITZEN CONTINUES
TO THE JINGLE BELLS,
A HO-HO-HO-TIVATOR HOVERING,
KIND OF LIKE
AN OFFICE CHRISTMAS PARTY
AT THE NORTH POLE, I'M GUESSING.
OHH!
AHH!
AND BARELY GOT A SNIFF
OF OUR $500 PRESENT.
WHAT, YOU REALLY EXPECT BLITZEN
NOT TO GET A LITTLE WOBBLY
AT THE CHRISTMAS PARTY?
JOHN, CHRISTMAS IS ABOUT
MORE THAN GETTING BLITZED.
IT'S ABOUT FAMILY.
THAT'S WHY AMANDA'S HUSBAND
SAM CIURDAR IS ALSO HERE TODAY.
JIMINY CHRISTMAS!
BLITZEN HAS A HUSBAND?
WHY, I BET HE'S THE BIGGEST
CHRISTMAS PARTIER EVER!
UH, MAYBE HE'S STILL IN
A FOOD COMA FROM THANKSGIVING.
JANGLE YOUR JINGLE BELLS
AT HIM.
(bells jingle)
WOW.
WONDER IF HE WAS A LITTLE
MORE JOVIAL WITH VANESSA.
IT IS CHRISTMASTIME,
SO DO YOU THINK YOU HAVE
THE CHRISTMAS SPIRIT WITH YOU?
BECAUSE YOU SEEM LIKE
YOU'RE READY TO GO.
UM, YES.
(John H., singsongy)
BORING.
I AM SO EXCITED.
LET'S DO THIS.
(yawns)
(normal voice)
TALK ABOUT EBENEZER SNOOZE.
I WONDER IF HE PERKS UP
IN COLD WATER.
WE'LL CERTAINLY
GET A CHANCE TO FIND OUT.
OHH, YI!
OH, GHOST OF CHRISTMAS REPLAY,
LET'S SEE THAT AGAIN.
HA HA HA!
OH, HO HO HO!
GOD BLESS US,
EVERY WIPEOUT.
WHAT A HEARTWARMING
CHRISTMAS STORY.
HOST OF CHRISTMAS PRESENT,
THESE THINGS YOU'VE SHOWN ME,
THESE WIPEOUTS--
ARE THEY REAL OR ONLY A DREAM?
NO, THEY--
THEY JUST HAPPENED.
WELL, CAN EBENEZER SNOOZE LEARN
THE TRUE MEANING OF WIPEOUT?
IS HIS FATE SET IN STONE?
YEAH, IT'S TOO EARLY TO TELL,
ACTUALLY.
WE HAVE 12 MORE CONTESTANTS
THAT NEED TO RUN THE QUALIFIER,
SO ANYTHING CAN HAPPEN.
(sighs) THANK HEAVENS,
THERE'S STILL TIME!
THANK YOU,
HOST OF CHRISTMAS PRESENT!
MM-HMM.
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
YOU KNOW, UNLESS THIS
IS MY HORRIBLE DREAM,
WE'RE GONNA BE RIGHT BACK.
WHO ELSE WANTS A CHRISTMAS HUG,
HUH? COME HERE, YOU!
OW. ALL RIGHT, THAT'S A "NO."
ANYBODY ELSE WANT A HUG?
HEY, GOAT!
COME ON! COME BACK!
Even though our mom tries,
she doesn't really get us.
And she'll never know
who we are, or what...
No way,
Madden Girls??
Nike!
They're so awesome!
Wow!
Yeahhhh!
Thank you!
Who's your mommy now?
It's a
Christmas miracle.
Give Victoriously.
Famous brands. Famously easy.
Famous Footwear.
Victory is Yours.
You could keep your phone and
I lonumber.hone.
But for half of what we pay now.
Half?
Really good progress today.
Welcome to the next generation
of family plans.
visit Net10Wireless.com
high pitched excited squeal
Yes! Thank you! Yes! Yeah!
excited screaming and jumping
Kids never get this excited
about clean teeth.
Yes, yes , yes!
But dogs do.
This season, give the gift
that makes dogs giddy.
And fights plaque and
tartar at the same time.
Greenies dental chews.
The treats vets recommend most
to make dental care fun
all year long.
♪
WELCOME BACK TO
THE "WINTER WIPEOUT--DECK
THE BALLS" CHRISTMAS SPECIAL.
THAT IS
ANOTHER SWELL SWEATER.
THANKS. IT'S BOATNECK.
YOU KNOW, ALL HOSTS OF MAJOR
TV SPECIALS DO COSTUME CHANGES.
MM-HMM.
YOU WANT ONE?
I GOT A WHOLE BAG OF 'EM.
NO, YEAH, ACTUALLY,
I LIKE THIS.
SUIT YOURSELF.
GET IT? "SUIT"?
MM-HMM.
(chuckles) 'CAUSE YOU'RE
WEARING A SUIT.
YEAH, I GOT IT.
THANKS.
SPEAKING OF HOSTS, WE SHOULD
CHECK IN ON THE NEW KID,
SEE HOW SHE'S DOING, YOU KNOW?
SHOW HER THE ROPES.
RIGHT.
I FORGOT TO TELL HER
NOT TO LOOK BALLSY IN THE EYE.
WHAT ABOUT
THE SECRET INGREDIENT?
(John H.) WHAT?
IS HE GIVING VANESSA
THE SECRET EGGNOG RECIPE?
DON'T BE JEALOUS.
I'M NOT JEALOUS.
I'M JUST DISAPPOINTED.
MAN, HE IS
A REAL PLAYBALL.
WOULD A LITTLE CHRISTMAS CARNAGE
CHEER YOU UP?
I MEAN, PROBABLY.
ALL RIGHT, THEN.
LET'S GO DOWN TO THE COURSE,
WHERE SANDRA TAYLOR
IS READY TO GO.
(high-pitched voice)
HA HA HA HA! HA HA HA HA!
THAT TICKLES!
HOLY COW. THAT IS A SPOT-ON
TICKLE ME ELMO IMPRESSION...
(air horn blows)
NOT UNLIKE THE ONE
LEFT IN MY FOREHEAD
AT THE MALL
ON BLACK FRIDAY.
LITTLE GIRLS ARE
DECEPTIVELY STRONG, JOHN.
AHH!
OH, HO HO!
TICKLE ME SANDRA GETS IT
RIGHT IN THE GIGGLE HOLE.
(laughs) YEAH!
THE NUTCRACKER
IS A PUPPET MASTER.
HE KNOCKED HER SILLY.
WELL, TICKLE ME SANDRA
WILL LOVE OUR CANDY CANES.
YOU KNOW, SHE RUNS ON CANDY...
AND DOUBLE "A" BATTERIES.
GREAT SNUFFLEUPAGUS!
WITH ANY BEST-SELLING TOY,
YOU GOT TO WATCH OUT
FOR CHEAP KNOCKOFFS.
TICKLE ME SANDRA'S
UP TO THE BIG BALLS.
LOBBYING SANTA FOR A SPOT UNDER
THE TREE--MARKETING GENIUS.
HO HO.
TICKLE ME SANDRA
GOES FLYING OFF THE SHELF.
OH, I'D WAIT IN LINE A WEEK
JUST TO SEE THAT AGAIN.
TICKLE ME SANDRA
AT THE TOP OF THE SNOWFALL...
(giggling)
AND GIGGLING
LIKE IT'S HER JOB.
OHH, HO,
MR. HOOPER'S GHOST!
THAT WAS A BELLY LAUGH.
WELL, HENSON THINKS
IT WAS AWESOME.
WHO ELSE
IS IN SANTA'S BAG?
FUNNY YOU SHOULD ASK.
I'VE GOT THIS IN THE BAG!
AND HE MEANS THAT LITERALLY.
MAN DESIGNS BAGS.
I LOVE ME SOME FANNY PACKS.
VANESSA, TELL ME MORE.
I AM DOWN HERE
WITH DAVID BRACKEN.
DAVID,
WELCOME TO THE SHOW.
INDEED. IT'S CHRISTMAS,
AND I HAVE A PRESENT FOR YOU,
A "WIPEOUT" BAG
THAT I MADE.
YOU GOT ME A PRESENT?
INDEED.
THIS IS BEAUTIFUL.
DID YOU MAKE THIS?
I DID. I MADE IT
OUT OF RECYCLED MATERIAL,
SO JUST LIKE "WIPEOUT,"
IT'S ENVIRONMENTALLY FRIENDLY.
(air horn blows)
(John H.) THE BAG MAN DAVID
IN THE UNFRIENDLY ENVIRONMENT
OF THE NUTCRACKER.
AND I'VE GOT THIS
IN THE BAG!
OHH, HO!
OH, HO! SWEET LORD!
HO HO HO.
THE NUTCRACKER PULVERIZED
EVERY NUT IN HIS BAG.
SANTA, PUT THIS IN THE BAG.
WOW, TWO SACK MASTERS
TALKING BAGS, JOHNNY.
IT'S A REAL
MEETING OF THE MINDS.
AHH!
BAG MAN DAVID
IS BAGGED AND TAGGED,
BUT THERE ARE
MORE CONTESTANTS TO OPEN.
YEAH, UP AHEAD,
EMERGING FROM BALLSY'S EGGNOG,
22-YEAR-OLD EMILY SPOONRONG IS
UNDER A FULL-SCALE ELF ASSAULT.
AH, HA HA!
OHH!
(Vanessa)
JUST IGNORE THE FLYING TOYS.
ABSOLUTELY.
IGNORE YOUR FEELINGS.
THAT'S WHAT THE HOLIDAYS
ARE ALL ABOUT.
SEE? IT'S WORKING.
SHE'S ALMOST TO THE END.
ALL SHE HAS TO DO IS
MAKE IT TO THE FINAL PLATFORM.
(quacks)
OH, HO!
OHH! WHAT THE DUCK?!
GOOD ONE. OUR CHRISTMAS DUCK
COOKED EMILY'S GOOSE.
AND WITH A TIME OF 5:42...
YEAH!
PROBABLY WON'T BE ADVANCING
TO THE NEXT ROUND.
WHERE'S OUR NEXT
CHRISTMAS STAR?
SHE'S BACK AT THE START.
18-YEAR-OLD AUTUMN BATES
IS GONNA GIVE IT A RUN.
THIS COURSE IS FOR NOOBS!
AND IN CASE YOU DON'T KNOW,
NOOBS ARE ROOKIES!
OH, YEAH.
I KNEW THAT, AUTUMN.
YOU DID?
WELL, DID YOU KNOW
THAT AUTUMN IS THE MASTER
OF FIRST-PERSON SHOOTER GAMES?
YES.
AUTUMN,
A.K.A. GamerGirl93,
HAS BEEN MY MULTIPLAYER NEMESIS
FOR THE PAST THREE MONTHS,
BUT SHE'S IN MY HOUSE NOW,
AND I'M ABOUT TO SCORE
SOME POINTS.
(snaps fingers)
GO! MY CONTROLLER.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I FITTED AUTUMN
WITH ONE OF OUR NEW GAMING VESTS
THAT WILL ALLOW ME TO CONTROL
HER RUN THROUGH THE COURSE.
JOHN, YOU CAN'T
CONTROL A CONTESTANT.
WANNA BET?
(air horn blows)
I'M GONNA SHOW HER
HOW IT'S DONE--
HIGH SCORE, NO WIPEOUTS.
OW. ALL RIGHT.
AFTER THE NUTCRACKER.
EVERYBODY WIPES OUT
ON THAT STUNT. IT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
BUT WATCH AS I ABSOLUTELY PWN
THE CANDY CANE.
DARN IT. SOMETHING'S WRONG
WITH MY CONTROLLER.
YEAH, LIKE,
YOU'RE NOT CONTROLLING HER.
NO WAY, ANDERSON. I GOT THIS.
WATCH. JUMP. JUMP!
OOH.
AW, MAN!
I ALMOST GOT TO THE FOURTH BALL.
SHOULD HAVE TURNED OFF AUTO-AIM.
(screams)
I'LL HAVE TO RESPAWN.
YEAH, YOU KNOW
YOU HAD ABSOLUTELY NOTHING TO DO
WITH AUTUMN'S RUN.
WHAT, JOHN?
DON'T BE SUCH A NOOB, MAN.
AND--AND THIS?
WIRELESS?
I'M GUESSING NOT.
COULD WE PLEASE JUST
GET BACK DOWN TO THE COURSE
AND SEE WHO'S NEXT?
WHAT TIME IS IT?
CHRISTMASTIME!
JIM CASHMAN KNOWS
HIS CALENDAR, JOHNNY.
WHOA. HE CAN
TELL TIME AND DANCE?
I GOTTA KNOW MORE.
VANESSA?
WHAT'S--WHAT'S
WITH THE COOKIE SHEET?
I LOVE TO BAKE COOKIES.
YOU DO?
I DO.
THAT'S GREAT,
YET YOU DIDN'T BRING ANY.
YOU JUST BROUGHT THE PROP.
YOU'RE A COOKIE TEASE.
IMAGINATION.
(John H.) I CAN'T HAVE
IMAGINARY COOKIES.
I'M ALLERGIC
TO IMAGINARY GLUTEN.
JIM THE COOKIE TEASE ON HIS WAY
TO FACE A VERY REAL SANTA.
THERE'S A GUY
YOU DON'T WANT TO PRESENT
WITH AN EMPTY COOKIE PLATE.
OH, HO HO!
AH, HA!
HOLY SNICKERDOODLE!
THE COOKIE TEASE
WENT ALL THE WAY
WITH THE JINGLE BALLS.
ALL PART OF THE SEASON
OF GIVING, JOHN,
AND OUR CHRISTMAS COURSE
GENEROUSLY PROVIDING
THE MERRY GIFT OF PRATFALLS.
THERE ARE ALL KINDS OF JOYS
FOR GOOD GIRLS AND BOYS,
LIKE CANDY CANE...
OHH!
OOH-HOO!
AND JINGLE BALLS.
AHH!
HOORAY! SNOWBALL FIGHT!
AND THE BEST THING
ABOUT CHRISTMAS? SANTA.
OHH!
HEY!
AND DON'T FORGET
THE ATTACK ELVES.
SWEET GUMDROPS,
THEY'VE GOT VANESSA!
OH, HO HO!
(deep voice)
MERRY CHRISTMAS! HO HO--NRR.
IT REALLY IS THE MOST WONDERFUL
TIME OF THE YEAR.
SAD TO SEE IT END, JOHNNY,
BUT WE ARE DOWN
TO OUR LAST CONTESTANT,
WHO'S WITH VANESSA.
THANK YOU, GUYS, SO MUCH.
I'M DOWN HERE NOW
WITH SHAWN TOWNSEND.
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
YEAH!
WOW, YOU'RE VERY EXCITED
ABOUT CHRISTMAS.
YES, MA'AM.
I-I LIVE FOR CHRISTMAS.
THE ENTIRE MONTH OF NOVEMBER,
JUST COUNT ME OUT,
BECAUSE I DON'T DO ANYTHING
BUT CHRISTMAS LIGHTS.
CAN YOU SEE IT FROM SPACE?
UNFORTUNATELY, YES.
(John H.) UNFORTUNATELY?
OWN IT, CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS!
YOU'VE GOT TO DO
SOMETHING THAT SAYS,
"I LOVE CHRISTMAS
MORE THAN YOU."
LET'S GIVE SANTA'S WORKSHOP
A LITTLE BLING, SHALL WE?
SEEMS LIKE A WASTE
OF ELECTRICITY.
NAH, WE JUST CUT THE HEAT
IN YOUR TRAILER.
UH-OH!
THE ATTACK ELVES LOOK HUNGRY.
HOLD ME.
NOPE.
OH, YOU HATE TO SEE
THE MINIONS OF SANTA
TURN THIS INTO
A HATE CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS CRIME.
OH, HO HO, MAN.
IT'S JUST TOYS, SHAWN.
THEY'RE JUST TOYS.
YES, BUT EVEN PLUSH TOYS,
DANGEROUS IN THE HANDS OF
HIGHLY TRAINED BLACK OP ELVES.
IGNORE ALL THE FLYING OBJECTS.
BE ONE WITH YIN.
(yells)
OHH!
AHH!
VANESSA, NOT EVEN YOU
CAN KEEP A MAN SAFE
IN THE FACE OF AN ELF ATTACK.
CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS
SURVIVES A LITTLE FRIENDLY FIRE
FROM THE ATTACK ELVES
AND WILL CONTINUE TO FIGHT
FOR CHRISTMAS CASH.
JOINING HIM
IN THE NEXT ROUND,
LOOK FOR
THE PENGUIN JESSICA KERR...
(Jessica) AAH!
AMANDA "BLITZEN" CIURDAR,
AND HER HUSBAND SAM,
EBENEZER SNOOZE.
ALSO STILL IN IT, WE HAVE
THE COOKIE TEASE JIM CASHMAN,
BAG MAN DAVID BRACKEN,
AND GAMER GIRL AUTUMN BATES.
STAY TUNED, AMERICA.
MORE HOLLY JOLLY "WIPEOUT"
AND AN ALL-NEW WINTER OBSTACLE,
STRAIGHT AHEAD.
THIS IS A WATCH
AND THIS IS THE TRIP
OF A LIFETIME.
COME TO JCPENNEY
TO GET YOUR OWN.
THEY'RE HOLIDAY BUTTONS:
LITTLE GIFTS THAT COULD TURN
INTO BIGGER ONES,
TO GIVE EVERY GIVER A CHANCE
TO GET SOMETHING TOO.
LIKE A GIFT CARD,
GREAT GIFTS FOR HOME
OR EVEN A GREAT AMERICAN TRIP.
WE HAVE OVER 20 MILLION GIFTS
TO GIVE AWAY!
THIS HOLIDAY SEASON,
VISIT JCPENNEY.
GET A BUTTON. GET A CODE.
GET ONLINE
FOR YOUR CHANCE TO WIN.
MERRY CHRISTMAS AMERICA.
TILL YOU FINISH YOUR VEGETABLES.
[ clock ticking ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THERE'S A BETTER WAY...
V8 V-FUSION.
VEGETABLE NUTRITION THEY NEED,
FRUIT TASTE THEY LOVE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
OR...TRY KIDS BOXES!
SCOTLAND!
AYE...AND DO YOU KNOW WHERE
YOUR LEUKEMIA TREATMENT
WAS DISCOVERED?
ST. JUDE!
RIGHT!
AFTER THREE UNSUCCESSFUL
MARROW TRANSPLANTS,
ST. JUDE CHILDREN'S RESEARCH
HOSPITAL DEVELOPED
A BOLD NEW FOURTH TRANSPLANT
THAT HELPED SAVE BRENNAN.
FORE!
I SAID FOUR. WHY YOU YELLING?
GOOD ONE!
GIVE THANKS FOR THE HEALTHY
KIDS IN YOUR LIFE.
AND GIVE TO THOSE WHO ARE
NOT. GO TO ST. JUDE DOT ORG
OR SHOP WHERE EVER YOU SEE
THE ST. JUDE LOGO.
♪
[ snoring ]
[ Male Announcer ]
INTRODUCING ZZZQUIL SLEEP-AID.
[ snoring ]
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S NOT FOR COLDS,
IT'S NOT FOR PAIN,
IT'S JUST FOR SLEEP.
[ snoring ]
[ Male Announcer ] BECAUSE
SLEEP IS A BEAUTIFUL THING.
[ birds chirping ]
INTRODUCING ZZZQUIL,
THE NON-HABIT FORMING SLEEP-AID
FROM THE MAKERS OF NYQUIL.
♪
WE ARE BACK
AND STILL DECKING THE BALLS
ON OUR ALL-NEW "WINTER WIPEOUT"
CHRISTMAS SPECIAL.
24 WISE MEN AND WOMEN
STARTED THE DAY,
BUT ONLY 12
FOOLISH ONES REMAIN.
THAT'S RIGHT, JOHNNY,
AND SANTA CLAUS WILL FILL
ONE LUCKY WINNER'S STOCKING
WITH $50,000...
MM-HMM.
THAT'S PROBABLY STOLEN.
SANTA DOESN'T
STEAL ANYTHING.
OH, SURE, HE JUST
SNEAKS AROUND AT NIGHT,
BREAKING INTO
PEOPLE'S HOMES.
TO GIVE THEM PRESENTS.
HE'S SANTA CLAUS.
OH. DO YOU MEAN
SAINT NICHOLAS?
OR KRIS KRINGLE?
OR IS IT FATHER CHRISTMAS?
DUDE HAS MORE ALIASES
THAN A MOB BOSS.
WHAT ARE YOU RUNNING FROM,
FAT MAN?
THAT IS KOOKY TALK.
LET'S JUST LOOK AND SEE
WHO'S STILL IN THE RUNNING
FOR OUR 50 GRAND, SHALL WE?
I'M WATCHING YOU, CLAUS.
STILL IN THE MIX, WE HAVE
THE HUMAN KAZOO CAREY CONLEY,
CHEST HAIR ARTIST
MICHAEL ANGELO GONZALEZ,
AND EBENEZER SNOOZE
SAM CIURDAR.
WE ALSO HAVE
TICKLE ME SANDRA TAYLOR...
(Sandra, high-pitched voice)
THAT TICKLES!
BAG MAN DAVID BRACKEN,
AND CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS
SHAWN TOWNSEND.
NOW THESE 12 WINTER WARRIORS
WILL SLUSH IT OUT
ON AN ALL-NEW CHALLENGE
CALLED PAIN IN THE ICE.
HERE'S HOW IT WORKS.
OUR CONTESTANTS
WILL START TOGETHER,
HUDDLED AROUND
THE ICE HOLE.
(imitates Hank Kingsley)
HEY, NOW!
CONTESTANTS WILL BRAVE
THE ARCTIC WATER,
DROPPING THROUGH THE HOLE
ONTO THE FISHING POLE
FOR A SPIN OVER
TO THE LANDING PLATFORM.
THEN IT'S A TRICKY BALANCING ACT
ATOP THE LUMBER TUMBLER...
OH, NO!
AN ICE-SLICK WALK
ACROSS THE WOODEN PLANK
TO THE OTHER SIDE.
WHOO-HOO!
THAT'S FOLLOWED BY
A PERILOUS TRIP
ACROSS
THE FROSTY FOOTBRIDGE...
OH, HOLD ON. HOLD ON. YEP.
FEATURING A RELENTLESS FREEZING
RUSH FROM OUR ARCTIC WATERFALL.
FINALLY,
THEY'LL MOVE IT OR LUGE IT...
WHOO!
WITH A BELLY SLIDE
DOWN THE SNOW CHUTE.
THE FIRST SIX COMPETITORS
LANDING SAFELY
ON THE FINISH PLATFORM
ADVANCE TO THE NEXT ROUND.
LET THE REINDEER GAMES
BEGIN, JOHNNY.
(cheering)
(woman) SOMETHING LOOKS
FISHY ABOUT THIS.
THOSE FISH ARE MEAN-LOOKING.
(Autumn) WHY ARE THERE
FISH ON HERE?
LIKE, WHAT FISH
SWIM IN ICE?
BECAUSE IT'S AN ICE HOLE.
WE'RE FISHING.
YEAH, GAMER GIRL IS NOT WHAT
YOU'D CALL THE OUTDOORSY TYPE.
(Sandra, high-pitched voice)
HERE, FISHY, FISHY,
FISHY, FISHY, FISHY.
TICKLE ME SANDRA'S SO CUTE,
IT'S STARTING TO BUG.
♪ 12 CONTESTANTS LEAPING
HEY!
"WIPEOUT" CAROLING!
♪ 11 BALLS A'... BALLS-ING
OH, BOY. I THINK SHE'S
MAKING THIS UP ON THE FLY.
♪ 10...
SNOWBLOWERS BLOWING ♪
♪ 9 CHRISTMAS DOGS
THIS IS FUN.
(air horn blows)
(John A.) MERCIFULLY,
THERE'S THE HORN,
AND CHEST HAIR ARTIST
MICHAEL ANGELO
LEADS WITH HIS ART.
CHEST FIRST ON THE FISHING PO--
OH! PAST THE PLATFORM.
GONNA HAVE TO GO AROUND AGAIN.
OHH!
HOLY DOG PILE!
EBENEZER SNOOZE'S ATTEMPT
TO SPOON IS THWARTED,
BUT CHEST HAIR ARTIST
HANGS ON
AND CAN MOVE ON
TO THE LUMBER TUMBLER.
GREAT SAVE.
HE NEEDS TO USE
THAT ROTATING PLANK
AS A BRIDGE
TO THE NEXT PLATFORM.
OH, NOT GOOD.
OH, HO!
HE IS
A HOT IMPRESSIONIST MESS.
TICKLE ME SANDRA GIVES
THE FISHING POLE A BIG HUG.
SHE'S ON TO THE NEXT SECTION.
GAMER GIRL--OH, HO--
OH, HO!
TAKES A DIRECT HIT.
TICKLE ME SANDRA WALKING.
(chuckles)
OH! GOES GONZO.
COOKIE TEASE JIM--
IMPRESSIVE HANGING ON.
THAT'S
A NONSTICK SWEEPER BAR.
ONTO THE PLATFORM,
AND HE CAN ROLL AHEAD.
GO.
CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS
LURED ONTO THE FISHING POLE.
PERFECT. HE'S MOVING ON
TO THE LUMBER TUMBLER.
TICKLE ME SANDRA...
OH, HO!
GIVES THE PLATFORM A KISS.
SHE IS SO LIFELIKE.
(David)
I'VE GOT IT IN THE BAG.
BAG MAN DAVID MAKING THE ROUNDS.
HE'S GOT IT.
COOKIE TEASE
GETTING INTO THE MIX.
HE'S ON TO THE NEXT SECTION.
YEAH, THE FRIGHTENING
FROSTY FOOTBRIDGE.
BACK AT THE HOLE,
EBENEZER SNOOZE TRYING AGAIN.
COME ON, BABY.
HIS WIFE CHEERING HIM ON.
OHH!
AY!
SLIPPERY LITTLE SUCKERS.
CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS--ANOTHER GO
ON THE LUMBER TUMBLER,
AND HE IS ACROSS
TO THE FROSTY FOOTBRIDGE.
YEAH, BUT NOT BEFORE
COOKIE TEASE ROLLS OUT.
LET'S GO, JIM!
OHH!
OH, HO!
COOKIE TEASE IS BURNED.
OVER AT THE START...
OH, DEAR!
OH, HO!
BLITZEN GETS SLOSHED
BY THAT SWEEPER ARM.
YEAH, BABE!
(Amanda) OW!
I GUESS
THE HONEYMOON IS OVER.
AW! DANG IT!
GO AHEAD AND GO!
CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS
GETTING COLD FEET.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO
TELL CHEST HAIR ARTIST TWICE.
HE'S NOT BIG ON
OVERTHINKING THINGS, JOHN.
YEAH!
OH, HO HO!
SAY WHAT YOU WILL, HE HAS
BEEN OUT FRONT THE WHOLE GAME,
AND NOW HE IS HEADED
FOR THE FINAL OBSTACLE.
CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS SLIDES
INTO THE FROSTY FOOTBRIDGE.
I CAN'T SEE!
WOW.
NEAR-WHITEOUT CONDITIONS.
(Jim) COME ON, SHAWN!
COOKIE TEASE
EAGER TO GO AGAIN.
OOH!
OHH!
COOKIE TEASE
GETS DOUBLE STUFFED.
CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS STILL NEEDS TO
MAKE THAT LAST TREACHEROUS LEAP.
WHOA, HO HO!
HEY!
CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS
HAS FINALLY MADE IT ACROSS.
(Shawn) THAT SUCKED.
CHEST HAIR ARTIST SET
FOR THE SNOW CHUTE.
BOSOM COVERED WITH FOAM?
TYPICAL.
OHH!
CHEST BLOCK!
EBENEZER SNOOZE TAKING A SHOT
AT THE LUMBER TUMBLER. MADE IT!
MADE IT.
I'VE GOT THIS IN THE BAG.
BAG MAN SHOWING THE CONFIDENCE
IT TAKES TO ROCK A MAN PURSE,
AND HE'S ACROSS.
CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS...
OOH!
TAKING HIS ENTHUSIASM
A BIT TOO FAR.
WAY BACK, GAMER GIRL FINALLY
DOMINATING THE FISHING POLE.
WAY AHEAD OF HER, THE BAG MAN
SLIDING DOWN THE SNOW CHUTE.
AHH!
OH, HO HO!
HE GOT IT IN THE WATER.
(giggling)
TICKLE ME SANDRA
SHARING A LAUGH
WITH HER PAL,
THE FROSTY FOOTBRIDGE.
GAMER GIR--
OH, LOOK AT THAT--
MAKES IT TO THE NEXT LEVEL
ON THE LUMBER TUMBLER.
TICKLE ME SANDRA
GOES, "WHEE!"
AND THEN GETS A BOO-BOO
ON HER JAWBONE. THAT TICKLES.
SUPERMAN!
AND COOKIE TEASE...
AAH!
OHH!
OH, HO HO!
DID YOU CATCH THAT, JOHN?
COOKIE TEASE PAUSES
FOR A SNACK BREAK.
AMAZING. NO ONE HAS
MASTERED THE SLIDE YET.
I CAN RELATE, JOHN.
IT TOOK ME THE FIRST
FOUR YEARS OF KINDERGARTEN.
GAMER GIRL, PLAYING IN
SEARCH-AND-DESTROY MODE,
IS ACROSS THE FOOTBRIDGE.
LOOKS LIKE SHE'S FOUND
THE CHEAT CODES, JOHNNY.
I'VE GOT THIS IN THE BAG.
♪ BAG MAN...
OH! OUT OF STYLE!
GAMER GIRL FLYING
THROUGH THAT LAST SECTION,
AND THE SAME THING HERE!
SHE STICKS THE LANDING!
GAMER GIRL,
THE FIRST CONTESTANT MOVING ON.
SO GAMER GIRL HAD AN AWESOME
COME-FROM-BEHIND VICTORY.
WHO'S GONNA BE NEXT?
(woman) FANCY MEETING YOU HERE.
COME HERE OFTEN?
PROBABLY NOT THEM.
CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS
LEADING THE GROUP,
AND HE BECOMES OUR SECOND
CONTESTANT TO LIGHT IT UP.
YEAH, BABY!
EBENEZER SNOOZE SLEEP-SLIDING
RIGHT THROUGH IT.
YES! HE TAKES THE THIRD SPOT.
THREE LEFT NOW.
YEAH! WHOO!
DID HE MAKE IT?
(man) HE'S GOOD!
WHOO!
BLITZEN HAS A REASON
TO PARTY NOW.
HER HUSBAND IS MOVING ON.
I GOT IT IN THE BAG.
YEAH, JUST KEEP TELLING
YOURSELF THAT, BAG MAN.
NO, HE'S GOT IT
IN THE SATCHEL.
WHOA!
TWO SPOTS OPEN,
AND TICKLE ME SANDRA
CLOSE BEHIND.
SHE GIVES HERSELF A PEP TALK
IN THE THIRD PERSON,
AND HENSON LIKES IT!
THAT LEAVES US
WITH ONE SPOT LEFT.
CHEST HAIR ARTIST LAUNCHES.
AH... SO CLOSE!
D'OH!
HE HAS BEEN AHEAD
THE WHOLE GAME.
HE JUST CAN'T
CLOSE THE DEAL.
THIS IS IT.
THAT LEAVES THE DOOR
WIDE OPEN FOR COOKIE TEASE,
AND HE HAS GOT IT.
"C" IS FOR "COOKIE TEASE."
THAT'S GOOD ENOUGH FOR HIM.
ALL RIGHT, GUYS,
WE GOT OUR SIX CONTESTANTS
MOVING ON
IN OUR CHRISTMAS SPECIAL.
MERRY CHRISTMAS!
EXCELLENT ACCOUNTING,
VANESSA.
STILL PLAYING FOR THE 50 Gs--
GAMER GIRL AUTUMN BATES,
CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS HIS OWN SELF,
SHAWN TOWNSEND,
AND EBENEZER SNOOZE
SAM CIURDAR.
ALSO STILL IN IT, WE HAVE
DAVID "THE BAG MAN" BRACKEN...
(David)
I'VE GOT THIS IN THE BAG!
TICKLE ME SANDRA TAYLOR,
AND COOKIE TEASE JIM CASHMAN.
BUT BEFORE THEY GET A SHOT AT
THE ALL-NEW WINTER WIPEOUT ZONE,
THEY HAVE TO FACE
ONE COLDHEARTED CHRISTMAS SNAKE.
TO PRACTICE MATH
MORE?
I LOVE MATH!
BUT TWO iPADS
MEANS TWO DATA PLANS?
THAT'S CRAZY.
MAYBE NOT.
WITH AT&T MOBILE SHARE,
ADDING AN iPAD
IS JUST $10 A MONTH.
BUT HONESTLY, MOM AND DAD'S LOVE
IS ALL I REALLY NEED.
WE SHOULD KEEP THESE
FOR US.
WE SHOULD KEEP THESE.
WHAT?!
[ Male Announcer ]
AT&T MOBILE SHARE.
ADD AN iPAD
FOR JUST $10 A MONTH.
ONE PLAN. UP TO 10 DEVICES.
AT&T. RETHINK POSSIBLE.
GINGERBREAD COOKIE COFFEES --
NO WONDER PEOPLE GET JOLLY
AROUND THE HOLIDAYS.
TRY DUNKIN' DONUTS'
HOLIDAY FLAVORS.
PICK SOME UP WHERE YOU BUY
GROCERIES, BEFORE THEY'RE GONE.
AMERICA RUNS ON DUNKIN'.
YOU SPEND ALL DAY COOKING IT.
SO WHY SPEND EVEN A MOMENT
CONSIDERING ANY BROTH
BUT SWANSON?
THE BROTH COOKS TRUST MOST
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
IN STUFFING AND MORE,
THE SECRET IS SWANSON.
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
Hey buddy, I bet Mom
would love this, huh?
Jack?
Jaaack?
Jaaack?!
Jack?!
Looks good
ladies!
Jack!
Come on,
stop the car.
JACK!
No, no, no, no, no!
The only thing more surprising
than finding the
perfect gifts..
Niice.
...is where you find them.
How did you know?
I had a little help.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
DISCOVER THE TEMPTING LAYERS
OF FERRERO ROCHER.
A WHOLE HAZELNUT,
SMOOTH CHOCOLATY CREAM
INSIDE A WAFER SHELL,
COVERED IN MILK CHOCOLATE
AND HAZELNUT PIECES.
♪
FERRERO ROCHER.
MAKE YOUR MOMENTS GOLDEN.
Bye!
Santa, we made a video for
your trip!
Yeah, you can watch it on your
sleigh!
OK!
Here you go.
Aw, thanks elves.
I also made you a video.
You are so sweet.
But you probably shouldn't watch
it on the sleigh.
Say goodbye to Santa boys!
Bye!
Good bye Santa!
Exclusively at AT&T, buy any
Samsung Galaxy smartphone,
get up to $100 off a second
Samsung Galaxy device.
♪
WELCOME BACK
TO "DECK THE BALLS,"
OUR FIRST-EVER HOLIDAY SPECIAL
HERE ON "WIPEOUT."
LITTLE HELP?
OH, JEEZ. JOHNNY.
THAT'S IT.
I'M MAKING A DOCUMENTARY,
"WHEN CHRISTMAS LIGHTS ATTACK."
WELL, YOU'VE NEVER BEEN
THE BRIGHTEST BULB,
HAVE YOU, BUDDY?
AH, HA--I DON'T GET IT.
WELL, WE'LL COME BACK AROUND
TO IT.
RIGHT NOW WE HAVE SIX
CONTESTANTS STILL IN THE RUNNING
FOR THE ULTIMATE
IN CHRISTMAS BLING, $50,000.
THEY ARE
GAMER GIRL AUTUMN BATES,
CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS
SHAWN TOWNSEND,
AND EBENEZER SNOOZE
SAM CIURDAR.
ALSO IN IT, WE HAVE
BAG MAN DAVID BRACKEN,
TICKLE ME SANDRA TAYLOR,
AND JIM CASHMAN,
THE COOKIE TEASE.
CLEARLY, DECORATING
FOR THE HOLIDAYS
IS HARDER THAN IT LOOKS.
SPEAKING OF WHICH,
WE HAVE A BRAND-NEW OBSTACLE
THAT IS SURE TO
CONFOUND AND AMAZE
OUR SIX CHRISTMAS CRACKERS.
YES. IT'S CALLED
THE COLDHEARTED SNAKE...
(hiss)
IN 3-D!
COLDHEARTED SNAKE.
YES, I NAMED IT
AFTER MY SECOND-FAVORITE
PAULA ABDUL SONG.
SECOND-FAVORITE.
YEAH, "VIBEOLOGY" JUST DIDN'T
MAKE SENSE FOR CHRISTMAS.
I GET THAT, AS LONG AS
IT MAKES SENSE TO YOU.
(hissing voice)
YES, TONS OF CHRISTMAS SENSE.
HERE'S HOW IT WORKS.
FIRST, CONTESTANTS
WILL MAKE THEIR WAY ACROSS
TWO SETS
OF SLITHERING SNOW SWEEPERS,
CIRCLING AROUND UNTIL THEY
MAKE IT TO THE NEXT PLATFORM.
FROM THERE,
IT'S ON TO PLUMMET SUMMIT,
A GIANT ROTATING SLIDE
THAT, AT ITS VERY TOP,
IS 25 FEET HIGH.
AAH!
TIMING CRUCIAL HERE,
AS CONTESTANTS ACCELERATE
DOWN AND OVER
THE SNAKE'S SLIPPERY BACK.
THEN IT'S ON
TO THE SHIVERING TIMBERS.
FIND A WAY ACROSS
THESE ROTATING WOODEN PLANKS,
ONTO THE SNOWBALL, AND ONE FINAL
LEAP TO THE FINISH PLATFORM...
AND YOU HAVE CONQUERED
THE COURSE. (hisses)
FIRST THREE CONTESTANTS
TO FINISH
WILL ADVANCE
TO THE WIPEOUT ZONE.
LET'S START UP THE SNAKE,
SHALL WE?
(air horn blows)
OUR CONTESTANTS UP THE RAMP
AND INTO THE ICY LAIR OF
THE COLDHEARTED CHRISTMAS SNAKE.
QUICKLY, EBENEZER SNOOZE...
OHH!
GETTING ROYALLY SCROOGED
ON HIS FIRST ATTEMPT.
CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS TAKES CHARGE,
FOLLOWED BY THE BAG MAN,
TICKLE ME SANDRA,
AND THE COOKIE TEASE.
THE BASES ARE LOADED.
AW! I GOT THIS IN THE B--
OH, HO!
OHH!
BAG MAN GOT IT IN THE GUT.
OH! AND THE SWEEPER
JUST TOSSED ITS COOKIE TEASE.
COME ON, SANDRA.
MAKE THAT JUMP.
OHH!
OH, HO HO HO!
"MAKE THAT JUMP"?
MAKE ANY JUMP.
HOW ABOUT STANDING
ON YOUR TIPPYTOES?
GAMER GIRL COMING AROUND.
SHE'S DETERMINED THAT THE LADIES
WILL NOT BE EMBARRASSED.
OHH!
OH!
OH, BOY.
CHECK IT OUT.
THE BAG MAN IS THE FIRST ONE
TO MAKE IT TO PLUMMET SUMMIT.
(David) GOT IT IN THE BAG!
(man) WHAT BAG?
IS HE HOLDING A BAG?
(man)
NO, HE'S NOT HOLDING A BAG.
HOW IS IT POSSIBLE THEY DON'T
KNOW HIS CATCHPHRASE YET?
IT'S ALL HE SAYS.
HE'LL HAVE TO
TELL 'EM LATER.
THE BAG MAN ASCENDING
TO THE PLUMMET SUMMIT.
AAH! OH, IN THE BAG!
OHH!
OH, HO! HOO HOO HOO!
HE CHECKED OUT AT THE EXPRESS
LANE AND BAGGED HIMSELF.
OH, IN THE BAG!
(crash)
OH, I THINK
HE BROKE HIS EGGS.
THE COOKIE TEASE--
HE LOOKS CUT OUT FOR THIS.
ALL RIGHT.
(Vanessa) GOOD JOB, JIM.
(Jim) THANK YOU, VANESSA.
DON'T CELEBRATE YET.
CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS
HAS CAUGHT THE COOKIE SCENT.
OHH!
CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS
CLEARLY HAS THE EXPERIENCE
FALLING OFF OF LADDERS
AND HANGING FROM THE ROOF.
LOOK AT THAT GRIP!
YEAH, BABY!
HE'S ON. COOKIE TEASE
OFF THE PLUMMET SUMMIT.
I HATE HEIGHTS.
MAKE SURE TO ADJUST
FOR HIGH ALTITUDE BAKING.
SHOOT!
OH, HO!
OHH!
WHEN THEY LAND
ON THEIR FACE...
I KNOW.
IT'S GREAT, RIGHT?
THE GAMER GIRL'S ADVANCING.
IS CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS DONE
DECORATING THE ROOFTOP?
THAT IS UNFAIR.
AH! NEGATIVE.
LOOKS LIKE
EBENEZER SNOOZE HAS ADVANCED.
THAT MAKES EVERYBODY BUT...
TICKLE ME SANDRA,
WHO'S STARTING TO SOUND
LIKE TICKLE ME GOLLUM.
(David) AIN'T NO THING.
OUR GAMER GIRL
RIDING THE SNAKE...
AW!
OH!
BUT CAN'T COMPLETE THE STAGE.
EBENEZER SNOOZE...
OH, HO HO!
OH! AND HE SUCCUMBS
TO THE SERPENT.
AND STILL TRYING
TO GROW--CATCH UP...
(high-pitched voice)
50th TIME IS THE CHARM.
TICKLE ME SANDRA.
OHH.
THERE YOU GO.
COOKIE TEASE LINED UP
TO PLUMMET THE SUMMIT.
OHH!
TIME TO COME ACROSS,
COOKIE TEASE.
AVOIDS THE WIPEOUT,
AND DOWN THE BACK
OF THE COLDHEARTED SNAKE,
WHERE HE'LL BE THE FIRST
TO FACE THE SHIVERING TIMBERS.
DUDE, CHECK IT OUT.
GAMER GIRL TRYING TO
MAKE IT A 2-PLAYER GAME.
THERE SHE IS,
SLIDING INTO ACTION...
CLEARS THE GAP
WHILE COOKIE TEASE LOOKS
TO PICK
A GIANT SNOWBALL FIGHT.
I DON'T LIKE WHITE BALLS.
OH, THAT WAS TERRIBLE.
OH!
AY!
YES, IT WAS.
EBENEZER SNOOZE...
(grunts)
AAH!
GOT THE DICKENS
KNOCKED OUT OF HIM.
HE IS A COLDHEARTED SNAKE.
LOOK INTO HIS EYES.
CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS
WORKING AS HARD...
(woman) WHOO!
AS THE JOLLY OLD ELF
ON CHRISTMAS.
(groans)
AND RESTING LIKE
IN THE DAY AFTER.
THESE TWO BETTER GET MOVING.
OHH!
EH, TAKE YOUR TIME.
COOKIE TEASE
AT THE SNAKE'S MOUTH.
BAG MAN AT THE SNAKE'S TAIL.
AAH!
OH! AND GAMER GIRL
IS ALL THUMBS.
BAG MAN DOESN'T APPEAR RATTLED.
(woman) WHOO!
AND WHERE DOES
THE FASHIONABLE MAN
KEEP HIS COLDHEARTED SNAKE
THIS SEASON?
IN THE BAG, BABY. LET'S GO.
WHO'S GONNA BE
THE FIRST ONE OVER?
I THINK WE CAN COUNT OUT
TICKLE ME GOLLUM.
UHH!
BAG MAN MAKES
AN AGGRESSIVE MOVE.
CLUTCHING
THE SHIVERING TIMBERS,
JUMPING TO MAKE THE SNOWBALL.
YES!
(Vanessa) YEAH. YEAH. YEAH.
NOW ONE HUGE LEAP TO QUALIFY
FOR THE WIPEOUT ZONE.
OH! YAY!
SOARING OVER TO SAFETY,
JOHNNY.
IN THE BAG!
WOW!
FIRST TRY!
IN THE BAG!
WOW. SOUNDS LIKE
EVEN HE'S GETTING TIRED
OF HIS CATCHPHRASE.
IT'S COOKIE TEASE...
(Vanessa) YES. YES.
DIGGING INTO THAT SNOWBALL
LIKE IT'S THE LARGEST
SUGARCOATED RUM BALL EVER.
(man) COME ON, JIM!
OKAY, ONE BIG JUMP FOR MANKIND.
WOW. HE NEEDS
TO STICK TO BAKING
BECAUSE HE BUTCHERED
THAT QUOTE.
AAH!
WOW!
OH! RATS!
LORD HAVE MERCY!
GAMER GIRL
SPRINGING INTO ACTION.
OVER THE SHIVERING TIMBERS,
ONTO THE SNOWBALL.
OH, MY GOD.
GONNA NEED A POWER BOOST
FOR THIS JUMP.
HERE WE GO. ARE WE GONNA HAVE
A LADY IN THE WIPEOUT ZONE?
OHH!
OH, HO!
(singsongy) IN THE FACE!
THAT'S GONNA HURT TOMORROW.
TOMORROW?
THAT HURTS RIGHT NOW!
(grunts)
EBENEZER SNOOZE
MIGHT BE A SLEEPER.
CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS DRAINING
THE ENERGY SUPPLY,
USING THAT GRIP TO OVERCOME
SHIVERING TIMBERS.
HE'S ONTO THE SNOWBALL.
(Vanessa) SHAWN.
OH, GOD.
CAPTAIN CHRISTMAS READY
FOR THE MOST WONDERFUL LEAP
OF THE YEAR.
MAKE IT HAPPEN, CAPTAIN!
(grunts)
OH!
OH, HO HO! HE LOOKS LIKE
ANOTHER FAMOUS CAPTAIN--
CRUNCH.
CHECK IT OUT.
IT'S EBENEZER SNOOZE OUT FRONT,
GOING FOR THE GIANT SNOWBALL.
AND... HE MADE IT!
CAN HE BORE HIS WAY
INTO THE SECOND SPOT
IN THE WIPEOUT ZONE?
(Vanessa) YEAH!
ALL RIGHT.
WE GOT OUR SECOND CONTESTANT
IN THE WIPEOUT ZONE,
AND IT'S SAM,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
REMARKABLY, JOHN, STILL
ON THE HUNT FOR THE THIRD SPOT
IS TICKLE ME SANDRA.
(normal voice) OH, MY GOD.
I MADE IT.
WHOA. WHAT'S WITH
THE WEIRD VOICE?
ADVANTAGE--GAMER GIRL.
REMEMBER, HER FIRST FINISH
ATTEMPT ENDED WITH A FACE-PLANT.
DON'T SHOOT YOUR EYE OUT,
KID.
(laughs) OH, NO!
OHH! NO!
SCORPION!
SCORPIONS AND SNAKES--
WE REALLY NAILED
THE CHRISTMAS THEME, DIDN'T WE?
WELL,
WITH THAT THREAT REMOVED,
THE OVEN DOOR IS WIDE OPEN
FOR COOKIE TEASE.
ON!
AAH!
MOSTLY ON! HE'S STAYING ON!
YES! ON TO THE MONEY ROUND.
YEAH!
THREE ARE MOVING ON
TO THE WIPEOUT ZONE,
BUT CHRISTMAS IS
ALL ABOUT GIVING,
AND THE OTHER THREE GAVE US
SOME OF THE BEST WIPEOUTS
OF THE ROUND.
I'M GONNA WRAP THESE UP AND GIVE
THEM TO SOMEONE SPECIAL.
CONGRATULATIONS, GUYS!
YOU'RE GOING TO
THE WIPEOUT ZONE!
(whistle blows)
YES, THEY ARE.
HEADING TO THE ZONE,
WE HAVE THE COOKIE TEASE
JIM CASHMAN,
DAVID BRACKEN THE BAG MAN,
AND "EBENEZER SNOOZE"
SAM CIURDAR.
(bells jingling)
UP NEXT, THE GIFT OF WIPEOUT
KEEPS ON GIVING
IN THE ALL-NEW
WINTER WIPEOUT ZONE.
(wind whistles)
Uh...
Um...
Hm...
Umm...
Uh...
Oh !
The Windows Phone 8X
by HTC on Verizon.
It features easy
to navigate live tiles
that are simple
to customize.
Just pin what matters most
right to your homescreen.
Exclusively with Data Sense--
a feature that makes the most
of you plan.
Only on Verizon.
OK KIDS, LUNCH.
BRAVO. BRAV...OH. IS THAT LUNCH?
YOU DESERVE A LITTLE
MOZZAREL-LA-LA-LA-LA-LA-LA.
WENDY'S.
GASP.
IS THERE SUPPOSED TO BE A PUDDLE
AROUND THE SNOWMAN'S FEET?
NO.
WENDY'S MOZZARELLA
CHICKEN SUPREME.
CRISP CHICKEN,
LOTS OF MOZZARELLA,
AND A RICH PARMESAN SAUCE.
MAKING TASTES THAT
MAKE THE SEASON.
THAT'S WENDY'S WAY.
NOW THAT'S BETTER.
GET A $10 TOYS-R-US
GIFT CARD OFFER
WHEN YOU PURCHASE A KID'S MEAL.
SEE OFFER FOR DETAILS.
CAMPBELL'S HAS 24 NEW SOUPS
THAT WILL MAKE IT DROP OVER,
AND OVER AGAIN.
♪
FROM JAMMIN' JERK CHICKEN,
TO CREAMY GOUDA BISQUE.
SEE WHAT'S NEW FROM CAMPBELL'S.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
WE ARE BACK ON "WIPEOUT'S"
FIRST "DECK THE BALLS"
HOLIDAY EXTRAVAGANZA,
AS SEEN ON TV.
'TWAS THE NIGHT BEFORE WIPEOUT,
AND ALL THROUGH THE ZONE,
OUR LAST THREE CONTESTANTS
ARE ABOUT TO GET OWNED.
OUR FINAL CONTESTANTS
SO LIVELY AND QUICK
PREFER 50 GRAND OVER A GIFT
FROM SAINT NICK.
BUT FIRST,
THEY HAVE TO TAKE ON
THE MOST FORMIDABLE
WINTER WIPEOUT ZONE
THE WORLD'S EVER SEEN.
(wind whistles)
AND IT ALL STARTS WITH
A SPINE-TINGLING 7-STORY DESCENT
DOWN KILLER LUGE.
FROM THERE, IT'S ON TO
THE SECOND OBSTACLE,
THE PSYCHEDELIC SNOW GLOBE--
A MIND-BENDING TRIP THROUGH
THIS SPINNING SPHERE,
WHERE CONTESTANTS MUST TAG
THE CENTER BUTTON
IN ORDER TO DROP
THE EXIT PLANK.
UP NEXT IS
THE FROZEN FURY,
AN UNFORGIVING
UPHILL BATTLE
TO JUMP OVER EACH ROTATING BAR
AND ACROSS TO THE OPPOSITE SIDE.
FINALLY, OUR LAST OBSTACLE,
ICED OVER.
NAVIGATE ACROSS
THESE REVOLVING DIAMONDS
TO THE FINISH PLATFORM.
(wind whistles)
WHICH ONE
OF THESE FINAL THREE
WILL TAKE HOME
THE CHRISTMAS CASH?
UP FIRST,
COOKIE TEASE JIM CASHMAN.
MERRY CHRISTMAS, BABY, MUFFIN,
AND BOO. HERE WE GO.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK
AT HIS JOURNEY INTO THE ZONE.
JIM "THE COOKIE TEASE" CASHMAN
LOOKED LIKE A PROMISING
CONTESTANT THIS MORNING
WHEN HE FACED THE QUALIFIER.
HE TOOK SOME SPILLS
AT PAIN IN THE ICE...
LET'S GO, JIM!
AND CAME IN
AT THE BACK OF THE PACK.
AAH!
AFTER A TOUGH RUN
ON THE COLDHEARTED SNAKE...
AAH!
WE'LL SEE IF HE HAS
WHAT IT TAKES
OR IF HE'S JUST A TEASE.
JIM CASHMAN READY
TO CHRISTEN
THE ALL-NEW
WINTER WIPEOUT ZONE.
IT'S GAME TIME.
OH, IT'S GAME TIME,
ALL RIGHT.
CUE THE LIGHTS.
HERE COMES THE COUNTDOWN.
(beeping)
SEVEN STORIES
OF TOUGH SLEDDING,
AND THERE GOES COOKIE TEASE.
OH, HO HO! YEAH!
WHOO!
OH, YEAH. LOOK AT HIM GO!
JIMINY CHRISTMAS!
JIM SLIDES DOWN
ALL SEVEN STORIES
LIKE HE'S COATED IN CANOLA OIL.
WHOO!
UNBELIEVABLE.
THAT WAS COLDER
THAN THE NORTH POLE.
THE ZONE'S SEVERE ENOUGH
IN THE SUMMER, JOHNNY,
BUT UNDER
THESE ICE-COLD CONDITIONS.
IT IS MISERABLE.
YEAH,
AND THE PSYCHEDELIC SNOW GLOBE
WON'T MAKE IT ANY EASIER.
CHALLENGE HERE--
TAG THAT CENTER BUTTON,
DROP THE EXIT PLATFORM,
AND JUMP TO THE OTHER SIDE.
HOPS ON AND GRABS HOLD.
NOW HE HAS TO CAREFULLY GET DOWN
AND TAG THAT BUTTON
IN THE MIDDLE.
OH! LOSES HIS FOOTING.
OH!
AAH!
OH! SO CLOSE!
OH! YEAH, TAKE A LOOK.
HE WAS WITHIN ARM'S REACH,
BUT THAT BUTTON
TAUNTING THE TEASE
AS HE FLAILS INTO THE WATER.
THAT FALL FORCING
A SECOND ATTEMPT.
I CAN DO THIS. I CAN DO THIS.
JIM TALKING HIMSELF INTO THIS.
GOTTA BELIEVE.
AGAIN,
HE ENTERS THE SNOW GLOBE.
A BIT MORE CAREFUL
IN BETWEEN THOSE PEGS.
GOT IT. HE'S TAGGED
THE CENTER BUTTON
AND THERE GOES
THE EXIT PLATFORM.
COOKIE TEASE
IN THE GREEN NOW.
EXIT PLATFORM
ALL LINED UP FOR HIM
IF HE CAN JUST GET
INTO POSITION TO JUMP.
OH, MAN. I'M MAKING THIS
A LITTLE DIFFICULT.
JIM WORKING ON SOME COOPERATION
WITH THE ROTATION.
GOTTA KEEP REESTABLISHING
YOUR POSITION.
LITTLE BEHIND HERE.
GOING FOR IT.
A BOLD MOVE! YEAH!
OH! I DIDN'T THINK
HE WAS GONNA MAKE THAT.
ON HIS WAY
TO THE FROZEN FURY NOW.
THE EFFORT AND THE EFFECTS
OF THAT COLD
STARTING TO TIGHTEN UP
THOSE MUSCLES.
(grunts)
LOOK OUT!
(laughs)
CAUGHT BY THE BAR
AND BACK INTO THE ZONE'S
FRIGID WATERS.
WHOA!
YEAH, COOKIE TEASE
JUST COULDN'T GET OVER,
AND HE HAS GOT TO BE
TURNING BLUE IN FRUSTRATION.
WHOA!
JIM BURNED UP A LOT OF TIME
WITH THAT 18-FOOT CLIMB
BACK TO THE FROZEN FURY.
HE IS UP AND OVER
THAT FIRST BAR.
KEEPS MOVING. HE MIGHT HAVE
THIS OBSTACLE SORTED OUT.
SURGING AHEAD,
CLEARS ANOTHER,
AND LOPES OVER TO THE SAFETY
OF THE PLATFORM.
WHOO!
TWO-THIRDS OF THIS NIGHTMARISH
WIPEOUT ZONE...
WHOO!
NOW IN HIS REARVIEW,
ONE OBSTACLE LEFT TO GO--
ICED OVER.
I'M AS TIRED AS SANTA CLAUS
AFTER DELIVERING PRESENTS.
YEAH, BUT STILL NOT HOME.
BELLY FLOPS FORWARD. OH, HO HO!
THE EXPLOSION OF
THAT WATER CANNON SO UNNERVING.
(laughs)
OHH!
OH! AND THE COOKIE TEASE IS
DUNKED.
YEAH, JIM CASHMAN TOSSED
HEAD OVER HEELS...
(slo-mo voice) AAH!
AND BACK INTO THE WATER FOR
ANOTHER LONG, EXHAUSTING SWIM.
CLOCK TICKING PAST
THE 14-MINUTE MARK NOW.
IT'S A DIFFICULT COURSE
TONIGHT,
BUT I DON'T KNOW IF THAT TIME'S
GONNA HOLD UP.
COOKIE TEASE
BALANCED AND STEADY
ON THE SECOND DIAMOND.
BEARING DOWN ON THE THIRD.
YEAH, CLEARS THAT GAP.
NOW FOR THE FINAL PAYOFF.
AND HE LANDS IT, JOHNNY.
YEAH. WELL DONE.
WHOO! ALL RIGHT!
JIM CASHMAN HAS FINISHED
THE WINTER WIPEOUT ZONE
WITH A TIME
OF 14 MINUTES, 25 SECONDS.
WHOO! YES!
HOPING TO BEST THAT TIME--
THE BAG MAN DAVID BRACKEN.
LET'S SEE HOW HE GOT HERE.
THE BAG MAN DAVID BRACKEN
GOT SACKED EARLY TODAY,
BARELY SURVIVING
OUR CHRISTMAS QUALIFIER.
PUT THIS IN THE BAG.
HE SHOWED HE COULD
WITHSTAND PAIN IN THE ICE...
OOH!
AND NOW AFTER COMING IN FIRST
ON THE COLDHEARTED SNAKE...
AAH!
HE'S HOPING HE'LL NEED A BAG
BIG ENOUGH TO HOLD $50,000.
BAG MAN READY TO GO
ATOP KILLER LUGE.
14:25 THE TIME TO BEAT.
THERE GO THE LIGHTS,
THERE'S THE COUNTDOWN,
(beeping)
AND THAT'S A 70-FOOT DROP.
WHOA, HO HO HO!
WAHOO!
SEALED AND DELIVERED.
ROLL BACK THE REPLAY
AND WATCH
AS DAVID STARTS DOWN
AND ACCELERATES
FOR THE FLIGHT OF HIS LIFE...
AAH!
BEFORE A CRASH LANDING
INTO THAT FREEZING WATER.
UP THE LADDER NOW
TO THE FANTASTIC
PSYCHEDELIC SNOW GLOBE.
(speaks indistinctly)
THAT BUTTON IN THE CENTER
IS KEY.
IT TRIGGERS
THE LANDING PLATFORM.
HELLO!
(laughs)
OH, THAT WAS GOOD, THOUGH.
BAG MAN TOUGHING IT OUT.
WORKING DOWN TO THE CENTER.
YEAH, THERE YOU GO.
RELEASES THE EXIT PLATFORM.
ALL RIGHT, NOW HE'S GOTTA FIND
A WAY OUT.
IN THE BAG, NOT THE DRINK.
MANEUVERING ACROSS
THOSE PEGS.
OH, DICEY DOWN ON THE BOTTOM.
OH!
REALLY BAD BODY POSITION.
AAH!
OH, HE COULDN'T HOLD ON.
OH, HO!
BAG MAN TRIED TO FLIP HIMSELF
ONTO THAT NEXT PEG...
(slo-mo voice) AAH!
BUT DIDN'T HAVE THE STRENGTH
TO HOLD ON.
NEARING THE 3 1/2-MINUTE MARK
AS HE STARTS
HIS SECOND ATTEMPT.
OHH! MAY BE
A LITTLE BRUISED THERE.
BAG MAN GETTING A BREAK, THOUGH.
PLATFORM ALREADY DOWN,
SO HE CAN CRAWL
DIRECTLY ACROSS.
AAH!
WELL-PLAYED.
YEAH. BAG MAN DAVID BRACKEN
MADE IT TO THE FROZEN FURY.
ALMOST TWO MINUTES AHEAD
OF COOKIE TEASE'S PACE
AT THIS POINT.
HE IS FLYING THAT.
LET'S SEE IF HE CAN EXTEND
HIS LEAD HERE.
HERE HE GOES.
STEPS ONTO THE PLATFORM,
A LEAP OVER. OH! WOW.
(grunts) AAH!
WHAT A LETDOWN, HUH?
WOW! ONE HASTY JUMP...
AAH!
AND DAVID IS SOAKING HIS BAG
IN COLD WATER AGAIN.
A LOT OF ENERGY SPENT
FOR A DO-OVER.
IT'S IN THE BAG.
A LOT LESS CONVICTION
IN HIS SMACK TALK.
COMING UP
ON 9 MINUTES NOW.
HE'S RUNNING OUT OF TIME,
BUT HE STILL HAS THE CHANCE
TO TAKE THE LEAD.
A LITTLE MORE
SURE-FOOTED THIS TIME.
CAN'T HAVE ANOTHER MISTAKE.
JUST ONE MORE SWEEPER BAR
TO GO.
CLEARS THAT ONE AND THEN
BOUNDS ONTO THE PLATFORM.
YEAH! BAG MAN DAVID NOW ON
THE LAST OBSTACLE, ICED OVER,
AND THAT PUTS COOKIE TEASE
IN THE PRESSURE COOKER.
BAG MAN LOOKING OVER
THE LAST LEG.
DROPS ONTO
THAT FIRST DIAMOND,
JUMPING FOR THE NEXT.
AAH!
OH!
OH! TORN UP!
BAG MAN JUST NOT GETTING
THE HANG OF IT.
(slo-mo voice) AAH!
OH! HIS TIME AND FACE
TAKING A BEATING THERE.
IT'S GONNA BE TIGHT NOW.
A LITTLE MORE THAN 15 SECONDS
TO FINISH THE COURSE.
HE'S ONTO THE FIRST DIAMOND.
GOOD THERE. 10 TICKS LEFT.
OHH!
HE BREAKS STRIDE, BUT GETS
TO THAT LAST DIAMOND.
BAG MAN LOOKING FOR
A CHRISTMAS MIRACLE RIGHT HERE.
LEAPING FOR THE LEAD.
OH!
OH, NO!
SO CLOSE!
BAG MAN CAN'T LAND THE JUMP,
AND 50K SLIPS
RIGHT OUT OF HIS BAG.
(air horn blows)
AND THERE IS THE HORN.
YOU HEARD IT.
AND THAT WILL OFFICIALLY END
THE BAG MAN'S RUN.
AH.
COOKIE TEASE JIM CASHMAN
REMAINS OUR LEADER,
BUT IS HIS TIME OF 14 MINUTES,
25 SECONDS GOOD ENOUGH
TO HOLD UP
AGAINST EBENEZER SNOOZE?
WHOO!
WE'LL CROWN OUR CHRISTMAS WINNER
RIGHT AFTER THIS.
(wind whistles)
Online Outfit
Piccolo
Headphones
Buy Now
Broadway Show
Megapixels
Place to Sleep
Little Roadster
War and Peace
Deep Sea Diving
Ninja App
Hipster Glasses
5% cash back
Sign up to get 5% everywhere
online through December. Only
from Discover.
TOMATO,
OBVIOUSLY.
HAHA. THERE'S MORE
THAN THAT THOUGH,
THERE'S A KICK TO IT.
WAHLALALALALLALA!
SMOOTH, BUT CRISP.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE DRINKING
A FOOD THAT'S A DRINK,
OR A DRINK THAT'S A FOOD,
WOOOOOH!
[ Male Announcer ] TASTE IT
AND DESCRIBE THE INDESCRIBABLE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
I made the clear choice.
Claritin-D.
Decongestant products on
the shelf can take hours
to start working.
Claritin-D starts to work in
just 30 minutes.
Power through
nasal congestion fast.
Get Claritin-D
at the pharmacy counter.
GO OLIVE GARDEN'S 2 FOR $25.
AN ITALIAN DINNER FOR 2.
START WITH ALL THE FRESH SALAD
AND WARM BREADSTICKS YOU WANT.
CHOOSE AN APPETIZER
MADE FOR SHARING.
THEN TWO DELICIOUS ENTREES
FROM FIVE OF OUR FAVORITES.
CLASSICS LIKE
EGGPLANT PARMAGIANA.
OR NEW FAVORITES LIKE
SMOKED MOZZARELLA CHICKEN.
THREE COURSES,
TWO PEOPLE, JUST $25
BUT ONLY FOR A LIMITED TIME.
GO OLIVE GARDEN.
AND TRY OUR UNLIMITED
HOMEMADE SOUP, CRISP SALAD,
AND WARM BREADSTICKS
LUNCH, JUST $6.95.
WELCOME BACK TO
THE CAN'T-SLEEP CONCLUSION
OF OUR "DECK THE BALLS"
"WIPEOUT" CHRISTMAS SPECIAL.
YEAH, WHERE IT'S BEEN ANYTHING
BUT A SILENT NIGHT.
HOT LIGHTS! WE'VE SEEN
TWO RUNS IN THE ZONE
WITH ONE STILL TO GO.
OUR LEADER,
COOKIE TEASE JIM CASHMAN,
CAME IN WITH A TIME
OF 14 MINUTES, 25 SECONDS.
AIMING TO BEAT THAT MARK,
A MAN WITH VISIONS
OF 50 LARGE DANCING
IN HIS HEAD--
EBENEZER SNOOZE SAM CIURDAR.
LET'S DO THIS! WHOO!
LET'S REVIEW HOW HE ARRIVED HERE
AT THE WINTER WIPEOUT ZONE.
WHOO!
EBENEZER SNOOZE SAM CIURDAR WAS
STINGY WITH EXCITEMENT
THIS MORNING WHEN HE RAN
THE QUALIFIER.
HE SLEEPWALKED THROUGH
THE PAIN IN THE ICE,
LANDING
AN UNEXCITING POSITION...
(groans)
BUT NOW, AFTER A CHANGE
OF CHARACTER...
WHOO!
HE'S GOT THE "WIPEOUT" SPIRIT
IN TIME...
AAH!
TO PUT HIMSELF IN STRIKING
DISTANCE OF THE 50K.
OUR MAN IN POSITION
ON KILLER LUGE,
FROM SEVEN STORIES
UP IN THE FROSTY AIR.
THE TIME TO BEAT--14:25.
(beeping)
THE LIGHT SHOW SIGNALS
THE START OF OUR SHOW.
EBENEZER SNOOZE IS OFF,
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
WOW!
AAH!
YOU SNOOZE, YOU LUGE, JOHN.
TAKE ANOTHER LOOK.
GAINING SPEED,
HE SKYROCKETS INTO THE AIR...
AAH!
AND THRASHES RIGHT INTO
THOSE FRIGID WATERS.
WOW.
WHAT DO WE DO HERE?
PRETTY STRAIGHTFORWARD.
YOU JUST GET IN, CLIMB ACROSS,
TAG THE CENTER, DROP THE EXIT,
LAND THE JUMP.
EBENEZER SNOOZE IN ACTION,
PICKING HIS WAY DOWN.
OH, BOY. BAD SLIP. OH!
OH, HO HO!
BAD RESULTS.
EBENEZER SNOOZE
SLIPS AND SLIDES...
(grunting)
PINBALLING THROUGH
THE SNOW GLOBE
WITH NOTHING TO HOLD ON TO.
(grunts)
HERE GOES NOTHING. UHH!
SECOND GO-AROUND
OF THIS THING.
STILL NEEDS TO REACH
THE CENTER BUTTON.
DONE.
(grunts)
EXIT PLATFORM'S IN PLACE NOW.
EBENEZER RUNNING JUST BEHIND
THE PACE SET BY COOKIE TEASE.
EBENEZER STAYING HIGH,
LOOKING TO MAKE THAT LEAP.
GOES FOR IT.
UHH!
OH, YES. SPOT ON.
NICE.
OH, SHOOT.
EBENEZER SNOOZE
ON THE FROZEN FURY NOW,
STILL WITHIN STRIKING DISTANCE
OF COOKIE TEASE'S PACE.
BUT IF HE'S GONNA CATCH UP,
HE HAS GOT TO MOVE.
STILL PAYS TO BE CONSERVATIVE,
JOHNNY.
IN THESE ICY CONDITIONS,
THE PLATFORM SO SLIPPERY.
STRUGGLING TO GET UP.
(grunts)
OH, NO!
NOT QUITE ENOUGH DISTANCE.
SHORTS IT.
EBENEZER SNOOZE DOESN'T GET UP
IN TIME
AND GETS ANOTHER
HYPOTHERMIC WAKEUP CALL.
THE WIPEOUTS, THE SWIMS,
THE CLIMBS--
ALL THREE BEATING UP
EBENEZER SNOOZE AND THE CLOCK.
BACK IN THE LINE OF FIRE
NOW.
OH! A LITTLE SCORPION HIT
ON THAT ONE.
OH, HO! CLOSING IN
ON 10 MINUTES.
SAM HAS A REAL CHANCE
TO PULL AHEAD OF COOKIE TEASE
IF HE CAN MAKE IT THROUGH.
EBENEZER'S WIDE AWAKE NOW,
JOHNNY.
ONE JUMP TO SAFETY, AND HE'S
GOT IT. HE HAS GOT IT.
OH, HE'S LOOKING GOOD.
INDEED. AN EXHAUSTED EBENEZER
HAS CAUGHT UP WITH
COOKIE TEASE JIM CASHMAN.
ONTO THE FIRST DIAMOND.
GOING FOR THE SECOND.
(grunts)
NO, SIR!
OH, HO!
SAM GETS THE SNOOZE
KNOCKED OUT OF HIM...
(grunts)
AND HE FACES
ANOTHER LONG, GRUELING SWIM.
THIS IS HIS LAST SHOT AT IT.
(grunts)
OH!
A GUT SHOT,
BUT IN GOOD POSITION.
HERE'S THE SECOND ONE.
(grunts)
POOR GUY. TAKING IT RIGHT
IN THE BREAD BASKET.
HE HAS THE FINISH
IN HIS SIGHTS.
JOHNNY,
20 SECONDS TO GET THERE.
$50,000 WAITING FOR HIM
IF HE CAN PULL THIS OFF.
16 SECONDS. JUST ONE JUMP AWAY
FROM VICTORY.
YES!
NO WAY!
YES! YES!
AND THAT IS THE MOST ENERGY
WE HAVE SEEN FROM HIM ALL DAY.
WHOO!
SAM, YOU JUST WON "WIPEOUT"!
EBENEZER SNOOZE SAM CIURDAR
BECOMES YOUR "WIPEOUT"
CHRISTMAS CHAMPION.
AND THAT WILL PUT A BOW
ON OUR "DECK THE BALLS"
"WIPEOUT" CHRISTMAS SPECIAL.
AND PLEASE DON'T FORGET
TO CATCH
THE ALL-NEW SEASON
OF WINTER "WIPEOUT."
WE'LL BE BACK RIGHT AFTER
THE NEW YEAR.
HAPPY HOLIDAYS, AMERICA.
I'M JOHN ANDERSON.
AND FOR OUR COHOST
VANESSA LACHEY,
I'M JOHN HENSON SAYING
MERRY CHRISTMAS TO ALL
AND TO ALL A GOOD NIGHT
AND BIG BALLS.
AAH! AAH!
OH!
AAH!
(grunts)
Captioned by
Closed Captioning Services, Inc.
AH!
AAH!
OH!
(woman) OH!
AAH!
OH!
JIM!
AAH!
(quack)
UHH!
(grunts)
DO I LOOK STUPID?
VERY REINDEER CHIC.
TONIGHT IT'S THE ROMANTIC
TELEVISION EVENT OF THE YEAR,
WHEN AMERICA'S FAVORITE
"BACHELOR" COUPLE,
ASHLEY AND J.P...
BYE, BOO.
I LOVE YOU, BABE.
FINALLY WALK DOWN THE AISLE
AND SAY "I DO."
"THESE ARE THE HANDS THAT WILL
TENDERLY HOLD YOUR FIRST CHILD."
YOU GOTTA HOLD IT TOGETHER,
'CAUSE I'M NOT GONNA
HOLD IT TOGETHER.
(laughter)
AND ALL OF YOUR FAVORITE
BACHELORS AND BACHELORETTES
WILL BE THERE...
OH, MY GOD!
THIS IS STUNNING!
TRISTA AND RYAN...
HOPEFULLY,
TODAY WILL GO AS SMOOTHLY
AS YOURS DID
NINE YEARS AGO.
JASON AND MOLLY...
WE GOT A BABY ON THE WAY.
AW.
EMILY...ALI...
JILLIAN...ROBERTO...
AND MANY MORE.