HEY, YOU KNOW WHAT?
GRANDMA HAS GOT A JILLION
CHRISTMAS CARDS TO SEND,
AND IT WOULD BE
REALLY HELPFUL
IF YOU WOULD TAKE
THESE REINDEER STAMPS,
AND PUT THEM ON--
NO, THANK YOU.
OH, SURE. NO ONE WANTS TO KNOW
HOW THE SAUSAGE IS MADE.
WHOA! HEY!
HOLD ON, LITTLE MAN.
WATCH OUT. YOUR HEAD IS
AT A VERY DANGEROUS HEIGHT
RIGHT NOW.
SO?
I HEARD THERE WAS SAUSAGE.
ARE WE FINALLY DONE
WITH THAT STUPID TURKEY?
NOPE.
MOM'S STILL PHONING IT IN.
COME ON.
IT'S A HOLIDAY LOGJAM, MIKE.
HALLOWEEN, THANKSGIVING,
CHRISTMAS.
AND SURVIVING ALL THAT
IS THE REAL REASON
I ALLOW MYSELF TO BE
OVER-SERVED NEW YEAR'S EVE.
YOU GOTTA LEARN
TO PACE YOURSELF, HONEY.
THEN YOU MIGHT ACTUALLY
GET TO SEE THAT BALL DROP.
(chuckles)
BEEN WATCHING 'EM DROP
FOR YEARS, DEAR.
I'VE BEEN WATCHING
STUFF DROP, TOO.
TOUCHE.
HONEY, COME HERE.
YOU WANNA HELP ME
WITH SOME OF THIS STUFF?
I'VE GOT ALL THIS--
YEAH, I'M SORRY
I HAVEN'T BEEN AROUND MORE.
IT'S BEEN INSANE
AT THE STORE.
YEAH?
OBAMA'S ECONOMY'S
HELPING OUT.
LOT OF PEOPLE CAMPING
THESE DAYS.
MOSTLY UNDER BRIDGES.
HEY, MANDY, COME HERE, HONEY.
I NEED SOME HELP WITH CHRISTMAS.
YEAH, I'M ALREADY
DOING MY PART
BY GOING AWAY TO CANCUN
WITH ALL MY FRIENDS.
PLUS I PRE-REGISTERED
FOR ALL MY GIFTS ONLINE.
HEY--
OOH, AND IF YOU ORDER TODAY,
FREE SHIPPING.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
KRIS, HE'S WITH
YOUR FOLKS ALL THE TIME.
HE'S NEVER EVEN
MET MY PARENTS.
WHY IS IT THAT EVERY TIME
I SAY "NO," YOU DON'T LISTEN?
THERE'S A WINDOW
INTO HOW WE GOT BOYD.
(mouths words)
RYAN WANTS TO TAKE BOYD
AWAY FOR THE HOLIDAYS...
TO CANADA.
WHAT? NO, NO, NO, NO. NO.
NOT--NOT CHRISTMAS.
CHRISTMAS IS A TIME
FOR FAMILY, LOVE, AND AFFECTION.
SO SCREW YOU.
MY FOLKS HAVE A BIG PLACE
UP IN WINNIPEG
WITH A FROZEN POND OUT BACK.
I CAN TEACH BOYD
HOW TO SKATE.
WHAT IF BOYD CRACKS
HIS HEAD OPEN ON THE ICE?
CANADA. FREE HEALTH CARE.
NO, HE'S GONNA HAVE
A TRADITIONAL,
GOOD, OLD-FASHIONED
AMERICAN CHRISTMAS
WHILE HE'S STILL
YOUNG ENOUGH TO ENJOY IT,
NOT ALL JADED AND GREEDY
LIKE THIS CREW.
HEY. I'M NOT GREEDY.
I JUST BELIEVE THE BABY JESUS
WOULD WANT ME
TO HAVE AN iPad.
-- Captions by VITAC --
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
HERE YOU GO.
(rips)
SORRY. THAT'S PROBABLY
MY FAULT.
I'LL WRAP THAT FOR YOU.
COME BACK IN A BIT.
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
KYLE, YOU GOTTA REMEMBER--
WITH TAPE, SHINY SIDE UP,
STICKY SIDE DOWN.
VANESSA'S BEEN REALLY
WORKING HARD.
I WANNA GET HER SOMETHING
SPECIAL FOR CHRISTMAS,
LET HER KNOW THAT SHE'S
REALLY APPRECIATED.
ALL RIGHT. LET'S SEE.
PERFECT GIFT. ALL RIGHT.
YOU HAVE A DOG, RIGHT?
MUFFIN?
VANESSA LOVES THIS DOG?
WE ALL DO.
OKAY, GOOD.
GO HOME, KIDNAP THE DOG.
YEAH. (mutters) JUST--
JUST HIDE IT SOMEWHERE.
NOW THIS IS IMPORTANT--
WRITE DOWN WHERE YOU HID IT.
VANESSA'S GONNA THINK
IT'S LOST.
SHE'S DISTRAUGHT. SHE PUTS UP
SIGNS ALL OVER THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
ED.
ALL RIGHT?
AT THE RIGHT TIME...
ED.
YOU FIND MUFFIN, ALL RIGHT?
YOU WRAP A BIG--WRAP A BIG
RED BOW AROUND HIS NECK,
AND IT'S A CHRISTMAS MIRACLE.
YOU'RE A HERO. THAT'S IT.
PLEASE, GOD, TELL ME
YOU HAVEN'T DONE THIS BEFORE.
MY ONLY MISTAKE WAS DOING IT
TWICE WITH THE SAME WIFE.
HEY. HI. HI.
HI, BABY.
HI, HONEY. HOW--
HELLO, MY DEAR.
HEY, ED, HOW ARE YOU?
HOW ARE YOU? GOOD.
UH, SO I WAS JUST
OUT SHOPPING.
I THOUGHT I'D STOP BY
AND SEE THAT SLED
YOU PICKED OUT FOR BOYD.
OH, OH, OH, IT'S
ON DISPLAY HERE. COME ON.
YEAH? ALL RIGHT.
YEAH, MUST BE TOUGH, HUH?
BEING OUT THERE ALL DAY,
AWAY FROM
YOUR BELOVED DOGGIE, HMM?
(mouths words)
I'M JUST PLANTING THE SEED!
(speaks indistinctly)
HEY, IF MR. ALZATE COMES BY,
WOULD YOU MIND TELLING HIM
THAT I TAUGHT YOU
EVERYTHING YOU KNOW?
(rips)
OH, AND DO YOU MIND
TEACHING ME
EVERYTHING YOU KNOW?
KYLE, THIS CAN'T BE TAUGHT.
I MEAN, SERIOUSLY,
IT'S SO SIMPLE,
IT LITERALLY CANNOT
BE TAUGHT.
IT'S POLYCARBONATE-BASED.
IT'S GOT A NYLON SEAT
FOR THE KID.
STEERABLE.
GERMAN ENGINEERING.
IT'S ABSOLUTELY
THE COOLEST THING.
HMM.
"TODES SCHLITTER"?
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
"DEATH SLED."
I'M GONNA KEEP LOOKING.
ALL RIGHT.
THINK YOU'RE MAKING
A MISTAKE.
BUT WHATEVER YOU GET,
WE'RE GONNA BUY HERE IN AMERICA.
I CAN'T BELIEVE RYAN THOUGHT
WE'D LET HIM...
TAKE BOYD TO CANADA?
YEAH, YEAH.
THAT WAS SOMETHIN', HUH?
BOY, WASN'T IT?
YEAH.
WHAT?
OH, NO, NOTHING.
JUST, UM...
WHEN, UH, WHEN RYAN
ASKED IF HE COULD TAKE BOYD,
THERE WAS A TINY
LITTLE PART OF ME
THAT KIND OF WENT, "YAY!"
WH... REALLY?
JUST A NICE,
NO-FUSS CHRISTMAS.
YOU--HONEY, YOU KNOW THIS
HAPPENS TO YOU EVERY YEAR.
YOU'RE JUST A LITTLE
OUT OF SORTS.
AS SOON AS YOU HEAR
YOUR FAVORITE SONG,
"THE LITTLE DRUMMER BOY"--
♪ PA RUM PA PUM PUM
YOU KNOW, YOU GET IT BACK.
YEAH, MAYBE. MAYBE.
I JUST KEEP THINKING
ABOUT HOW SIMPLE CHRISTMAS WAS
WHEN IT WAS JUST
YOU AND ME, YOU KNOW?
A LITTLE APARTMENT
ON LEETSDALE DRIVE, REMEMBER?
YEAH, I DO. SURE, I DO.
YEAH.
WE'D SLEEP IN,
THEN GO TO CHURCH.
I'D SLEEP IN CHURCH.
YEAH. (sighs)
GOD, IT WAS SO QUIET,
WE COULD HEAR
WHEN THE UPSTAIRS NEIGHBOR
FELL TO THE FLOOR.
YEAH.
CHRISTMAS STROKE.
"OH!" (imitates thud)
(laughs)
AND REMEMBER?
THE E.M.S. GUYS
SHOWED UP IN SANTA HATS.
I THOUGHT THAT WAS
INAPPROPRIATE. I REALLY DID.
YEAH.
GOOD TIMES. GOOD TIMES.
YEAH, GOOD TIMES, YEAH.
SO YOU, UH, WANNA DO
CHRISTMAS WITHOUT THE KIDS?
UH, NO.
NO, NO, NO, NO.
I CAN'T EVEN
IMAGINE CHRISTMAS
WITHOUT KRISTIN AND MANDY
AND EVE AND BOYD, AND...
BOYD, RIGHT, RIGHT.
YEAH. JUST... THE HOUSE
WOULD BE SO EMPTY.
(clicks tongue)
QUIET. YEAH.
YEAH, I MEAN, IF YOU WERE UNDER
THE TREE, I'D UNWRAP YOU.
(both laugh)
I'M GONNA PUT YOU
ON THE "NAUGHTY" LIST.
(laughs)
(laughs) OH...
OKAY. THAT'D BE FUN, YEAH.
THAT'D BE--
WELL, WE GOT
A LITTLE, UH...
YEAH.
OH. HONEY...
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
WELL, I GOTTA GO
WAIT IN LINE AT THE HAM STORE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
THAT'S CODE FOR, BUT I'M IN.
(thud)
FINALLY GIVING THAT BIRD
A RESPECTABLE SEND-OFF?
I'VE GIVEN THIS BIRD
A RESPECTABLE SEND-OFF
EVERY MORNING ABOUT 8:05.
HEY, THANKS FOR SUPPORTING ME
WITH RYAN, BY THE WAY.
SOME NERVE OF THAT GUY,
THINKING HE COULD TAKE
BOYD OUT OF THE COUNTRY
TO WANNABE-AMERICA
FOR CHRISTMAS.
ON THE OTHER HAND,
MAYBE BOYD WOULD LIKE IT THERE.
THEY GOT MOUNTIES,
THEY GOT MAPLE SYRUP,
THEY GOT, UM... WELL...
YOU CAN GOOGLE IT. I'M SURE
THERE'S A LOT OF STUFF UP THERE
THAT KIDS LIKE.
I'M ALL FOR
THE VOGELSONS MEETING BOYD.
I JUST DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHY IT HAS TO BE AT CHRISTMAS.
YEAH, LET 'EM SPEND TIME
WITH THEIR OTHER GRANDCHILDREN.
NO, RYAN'S AN ONLY CHILD.
REALLY?
SO THEY LOOKED AT HIM
AFTER HE WAS BORN AND SAID,
"CAN'T DO BETTER
THAN THAT, EH?"
WAIT, SHOULD I--
SHOULD I HAVE LET BOYD GO?
GO WHERE?
OH, KRIS IS HAVING
SECOND THOUGHTS
ABOUT BOYD GOING TO CANADA.
WHAT KIND OF MOM
WOULD THAT MAKE ME?
NOT BEING
WITH MY KID AT CHRISTMAS?
UM, IT'S, UH,
NOT THE MOST TERRIBLE THING
I'VE EVER... HEARD.
YEAH. IF THERE'S SOME WAY
THAT YOU COULD DO IT
WHERE YOU WOULDN'T
HAVE TO BE SEPARATED,
YOU COULD, UH...
WELL, YOU COULD GO WITH HIM.
SERIOUSLY?
GOT PLENTY OF ROOM UP THERE.
CANADIANS DON'T SHUT UP
ABOUT THEIR WIDE-OPEN SPACES.
NO, I DON'T WANT TO
RUIN YOUR GUYS' CHRISTMAS.
OH, HEY, COME ON.
IT'S GONNA BE QUIET,
BUT WE'RE GONNA BE FINE HERE.
WE REALLY WILL.
(mouths word)
ALL RIGHT. I GUESS I'LL GO
CHECK INTO SOME FLIGHTS.
YEAH, CHECK--
YEAH, SURE, JUST CHECK IN.
SEE HOW--YEAH, THAT'D BE
ALL RIGHT, RIGHT, HONEY?
SHOULD BE... (mouths words)
(both laughing)
(lowered voice) YOU'RE DOING IT!
YOU'RE DOING IT!
QUIET! QUIET! QUIET!
I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU'RE ACTUALLY
BUMPING OFF THE KIDS.
(whispers) QUIET.
(normal voice) MERRY CHRISTMAS.
IT'S YOUR PRESENT.
OHH!
(normal voice) NO.
YOU KNOW WHAT? THIS IS NOT GOOD.
HONEY--
THIS IS WRONG. I DON'T
FEEL GOOD ABOUT THIS.
I DON'T WANT TO--
HONEY, YOUR HANDS ARE CLEAN.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
WE GOT MANDY
TAKEN CARE OF.
YEAH.
KRISTIN AND BOYD.
JUST GOT ONE MORE KID
TO GET RID OF.
EVE.
NO NAMES. NO NAMES.
THE LESS YOU KNOW,
THE BETTER.
BUT SHE'S GONNA
BE A PROBLEM.
ALL RIGHT, LET ME THINK OF
SOMETHING. HOLD ON A SECOND.
WAIT A MINUTE.
WAIT A MINUTE. HO--
YOU DIDN'T HEAR THIS FROM ME,
BUT....
THE GOLDSTEINS INVITED EVE
TO GO WITH THEM TO ASPEN
OVER THE HOLIDAYS,
BUT SOMEONE INSISTED THAT SHE
NEEDED TO WORK AT OUTDOOR MAN.
I KNOW SOMEBODY
WHO KNOWS SOMEBODY
WHO CAN MAKE THAT GO AWAY.
(chuckles)
NO MUSS, NO FUSS?
LIKE IT NEVER EVEN HAPPENED.
LET'FOR AN IDEA.S -
A GRAND IDEA CALLED AMERICA.
THE IDEA THAT
IF YOU WORK HARD,
IF YOU HAVE A DREAM,
IF YOU WORK WITH
YOUR NEIGHBORS...
YOU CAN DO MOST ANYTHING.
THIS LED TO OTHER IDEAS
LIKE LIBERTY
AND ROCK 'N' ROLL.
TO FREE MARKETS,
FREE ENTERPRISE,
AND FREE REFILLS.
IT PUT A MAN ON THE MOON
AND A PHONE IN YOUR POCKET.
OUR COUNTRY'S GONE THROUGH A LOT
OVER THE CENTURIES AND A HALF.
BUT THIS IDEA ISN'T FRAGILE.
WHEN TIMES GET TOUGH,
IT RALLIES US AS ONE.
EVERY DAY, MORE PEOPLE
BELIEVE IN THE AMERICAN IDEA
AND WHEN THEY DO,
THE DREAM COMES TRUE.
WE'RE GRATEFUL
TO BE A PART OF IT.
It's a morning breeze
smooth as Black Silk.
With Folgers Gourmet Selections
K-Cup packs
You can turn any day gourmet.
New roasts, a new look...
available
where you buy groceries.
[ Male Announcer ]
WATCH OUT, CASANOVA.
THERE'S A NEW LADIES' MAN
IN TOWN,
AND HE KNOWS TO SHOP AT
Walgreens DURING THE HOLIDAYS.
WE HAVE GREAT GIFTS
AT GREAT PRICES,
ONLINE AND IN THE STORE.
SO YOU'RE SURE TO FIND
SOMETHING
FOR THAT SPECIAL SOMEONE --
EVEN IF YOU HAVE
SEVERAL SPECIAL SOMEONES.
SHOP Walgreens FOR GREAT GIFTS,
LIKE Lindt Lindor Truffles,
AND GET UP TO 10,000
Balance Rewards POINTS
ON YOUR TOTAL PURCHASE, HERE.
At THE Corner
OF Happy AND Healthy.
(Kyle) HEY, MR. B.
JUST WANTED TO LET YOU KNOW,
I FIRED EVE
LIKE YOU TOLD ME TO.
OH.
SHE DIDN'T TAKE IT WELL.
SHE SAID SOME THINGS.
SCARY THINGS.
WOULD YOU MIND
WALKING ME TO MY CAR LATER?
MIKE, I'VE DONE
A TERRIBLE THING.
WHAT'S UP, ED?
UH, KYLE, CLOSE THE DOOR.
WHAT HAPPENED?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
OH...
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
ALL RIGHT, LOOK...
WHAT YOU'RE ABOUT TO SEE
MAY SICKEN YOU.
PLEASE TELL ME YOU DIDN'T
KIDNAP MY DOG.
NO. SWEAR ON YOUR LIFE
YOU'LL TELL NO ONE.
YEAH, YEAH, NOTHIN'.
WHAT IS IT, ED?
NO--OKAY. OKAY.
(plastic crackles)
YOU SHOT A BALD EAGLE.
YEP. THAT'S HIM,
ALL RIGHT.
OH...
I'M SO ASHAMED
FOR THE CRIME I'VE COMMITTED
AGAINST MY COUNTRY.
ON THE OTHER HAND,
I BAGGED A FRIGGIN' EAGLE.
GOOD GOIN', ED.
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT.
I HAD THE TURKEY IN MY SIGHTS.
I WAS ABOUT TO
SQUEEZE OFF A SHOT
WITH MY S20 TURKEY THUMPER
WHEN THIS...
BALD IDIOT SWOOPS IN.
YOU'RE GONNA
GET FINED FOR THIS, ED.
OH, THEY HAVE TO
CATCH ME FIRST.
THAT SHOULDN'T BE TOO HARD.
IT'S GOT A GPS
AROUND ITS NECK.
THEY'RE STILL
TAGGING EAGLES?
THEY'RE NOT EVEN
ENDANGERED ANYMORE.
UNLESS YOU'RE NEARBY
WITH A TURKEY THUMPER.
YOU GOTTA
GET BALDY OUT OF HERE.
I'M ON IT.
YEAH.
COME WITH ME, MR. ALZATE.
NO! (shouts indistinctly)
HE'S TALKING
ABOUT THE EAGLE.
WE HAVE TO DISPOSE OF THIS
PROPERLY.
I KNOW A PLACE
WE CAN DUMP THIS.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO
HOLD DOWN THE STORE.
NO PROBLEM.
ACTUALLY, ONCE ONE OF THESE
TOUCHES THE GROUND,
AREN'T YOU SUPPOSED TO
BURN IT?
THAT'S FOR FLAGS,
YOU BONEHEAD.
I'M NOT THE ONE
WHO SHOT AN EAGLE.
SO, MANDY'S OFF
TO MEXICO IN A WEEK.
OH.
AND KRISTIN BOOKED CANADA.
GONNA BE GONE
TILL THE 28th.
RIGHT.
AND HOW DID IT GO
WITH FIRING EVE?
REALLY WELL.
CHRISTMAS WITH THE GOLDSTEINS
IN ASPEN.
THERE'S A HOLIDAY SPECIAL
YOU'LL NEVER SEE.
THANK YOU, BABY.
(clink)
(laughs)
WE SUCCESSFULLY KILLED
OUR FAMILY CHRISTMAS.
YEAH.
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT'S GONNA BE
JUST THE TWO OF US.
I KNOW.
GOSH, I SHOULDN'T HAVE
BOUGHT A 20-POUND HAM.
CHALLENGE ACCEPTED.
NO, YOU HAVE TO GO
TO CANCUN.
I AM NOT GOING.
LISTEN, IF YOU DON'T GO,
NONE OF US CAN GO,
AND I WILL HAVE TO
STAY HOME WITH MY FAMILY,
WHICH WILL SUCK.
I'LL HANDLE THIS.
YOU DON'T KNOW NUTTIN'.
I DON'T KNOW NUTTIN'.
GIRLS, GIRLS, GIRLS,
WHAT'S ALL THE YELLING ABOUT?
OKAY, CHLOE'S BOYFRIEND STEVE
MADE OUT WITH LESLIE,
WHO JUST BROKE UP WITH TREVOR
AT ZACH'S PARTY,
SO NOW CHLOE DOESN'T WANNA
GO TO CANCUN,
SO THE WHOLE TRIP
IS FALLING APART.
WELL, THAT CAN'T
STOP YOU FROM GOING.
CHLOE'S A DRAG.
YOU'VE ALWAYS SAID THAT.
I'M CHLOE.
NOT CHLOE.
I MEAN THE GIRL THAT CRIED
AT YOUR BIRTHDAY PARTY
'CAUSE SHE HAS
REAL FAT CALVES.
THAT WAS ALSO ME.
LISTEN, YOU'RE GETTING ME
OFF POINT HERE.
THIS IS A GREAT TRIP.
THERE MUST BE A SIMPLE,
EASY WAY TO FIX THIS.
ALL RIGHT. ENOUGH.
LET ME GET THIS
STRAIGHT, STEVE--
THE ONLY REASON
THAT YOU KISSED LESLIE
WAS 'CAUSE YOU WERE
AT ZACH'S PARTY
AND THIS GIRL CAMILLE
DARED YOU TO DO IT?
NO. KATRINA DARED HIM
BECAUSE SHE USED TO
HAVE A CRUSH ON STEVE.
SO STEVE KISSED HER
BECAUSE HE WAS DARED,
AND A REAL MAN
DOESN'T RUN FROM A DARE.
SO WHAT YOU ACTUALLY
HAVE HERE IS,
WHOO, A REAL MAN.
WOW. I NEVER
THOUGHT OF IT THAT WAY.
WHAT A SURPRISE.
SO WE'RE GOIN' TO CANCUN?
(Chloe) YES!
ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU, DAD.
(squeals)
MAN, OH, MAN.
WELL, WELL, WELL.
YEAH. HEY, EVE.
WHAT'S UP?
I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE UP TO,
OLD MAN.
SENDING KRISTIN
OFF TO THE FROZEN NORTH.
KNOCKIN' OFF ME AND MANDY.
YOU WANNA CLEAR OUT
THE HOUSE,
SPEND SOME ALONE TIME WITH
YOUR LITTLE LADY FRIEND, HEH?
HMM. WHAT IF I SUDDENLY
WASN'T IN THE MOOD FOR SKIING?
ALL RIGHT.
I'LL PLAY ALONG.
WHAT'LL IT TAKE
TO HAVE THIS GO AWAY?
WELL... (sighs)
THERE'S A REPORT CARD COMIN'.
I WANT YOU TO SIGN IT.
NO QUESTIONS ASKED.
WHY?
I SAID, NO QUESTIONS.
IS THAT A DEAL?
ALL RIGHT.
LISTEN, HOW--HOW BAD
A REPORT CARD WAS IT?
I'M GETTING A "D"
IN ART.
A "D" IN ART?
I-I CAN'T
DRAW HANDS, OKAY?
THEY ALWAYS END UP
LOOKING LIKE A BUNCH OF BANANAS.
WELL, WHAT DO
YOUR BANANAS LOOK LIKE?
(scoffs) YOU DO NOT
WANNA KNOW.
WoWooohooo....Hahaahahaha!
Oh...there you go.
Wooohooo....Hahaahahaha!
I'm gonna stand
up to her!
No you're not.
I know.
You know Ronny folks who save
hundreds of dollars
switching to GEICO
sure are happy.
How happy are they Jimmy?
Happier than a witch in
a broom factory.
Get happy. Get GEICO.
Fifteen minutes could save you
fifteen percent or more.
[ Female Announcer ]
THE CRAVINGOOOH.CHOCOLATE...
...IS ALL GROWN UP.
OOOH.
[ Female Announcer ]
JARED PRESENTS BEAUTIFUL,
NATURAL LEVIAN
CHOCOLATE DIAMONDS
AND CHOCOLATE CULTURED
SOUTH SEA PEARLS.
LEVIAN IS THE ONLY COMPANY
ON EARTH
TO MAKE JEWELRY
WITH CHOCOLATE DIAMONDS.
LEVIAN -- THE LEADING FAMILY
IN JEWELRY --
FROM ANCIENT ROYALTY
TO TODAY'S RED CARPET.
YOU WILL ONLY FIND THESE STYLES
AT JARED.
LEVIAN CHOCOLATE DIAMONDS,
THEY'RE ANYTHING...BUT VANILLA.
THAT'S WHY HE WENT TO JARED...
THE GALLERIA OF JEWELRY.
I'M TELLING YOU,
THEY'RE TRACKING US, I KNOW IT.
I CAN'T GET CAUGHT.
GUYS WITH LONG HAIR
AND SLENDER FRAMES--
THEY DON'T DO WELL
IN THE CLINK.
(thuds)
WHAT THE HELL WAS THAT?
ED, DID WE HIT SOMETHING?
WITH MY LUCK, I PROBABLY
RAN OVER UNCLE SAM.
(thuds)
WHAT THE HELL WAS THAT?
DO WE HAVE A FLAT?
(loud thudding)
NO, THAT'S NO FLAT.
(thudding continues)
I BETTER PULL OVER
AND SEE.
BOYD, WHAT ARE YOU DOING UP?
YOU SHOULD BE IN BED.
YOU'RE PUTTING CHRISTMAS AWAY?
WELL, HONEY,
YOU'RE NOT GONNA BE HERE.
IT'S JUST GONNA BE
ME AND GRANDPA.
BUT I WANNA SEE YOU
ON CHRISTMAS.
WELL, YOU'LL BE WITH YOUR
OTHER GRANDMA AND GRANDPA.
IT WON'T BE THE SAME.
NO. NO, IT WON'T, HONEY.
WHAT'S, UH,
WHAT'S THAT YOU GOT THERE?
IT'S MY NEW TOY.
AH.
(instrumental
"Little Drummer Boy" playing)
♪ PA RUM PA PUM PUM
♪
(clicks tongue)
♪ BA RUM PA PUM PUM
(sighs)
♪
(car doors close)
(thudding)
POP THE TRUNK.
COME ON. POP THE TRUNK.
ON THREE.
ONE...
TWO...
(screeching)
WHY DOES THIS PLACE
SMELL LIKE AN AIR FRESHENER?
PLEASE TELL ME YOU'RE GONNA
HANG THIS
FROM YOUR MIRROR IN YOUR CAR.
NO.
I HEARD THAT CHRISTMAS CAROL,
"THE LITTLE DRUMMER BOY."
IT JU--IT ALWAYS GETS TO ME.
AND REMEMBER
THAT WONDERFUL VERSION
WITH BING CROSBY
AND DAVID BOWIE?
WARM CHRISTMAS MEMORIES.
YEAH.
ZIGGY STARDUST SINGING
WITH A CROONER
WHO KNOCKED HIS KIDS AROUND.
SO YOU'VE COMPLETELY
CHANGED YOUR MIND?
HONEY, I CAN'T STAND THE THOUGHT
OF WAKING UP CHRISTMAS MORNING
AND NOT HAVING
THE GIRLS HERE.
AND BOYD.
BOYD.
(exhales deeply)
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT,
ALL RIGHT.
I GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF WORK TO DO THEN.
BUT, HONEY, I MEAN,
THIS IS CRAZY.
ISN'T IT TOO LATE?
I EAT A COUPLE AIRFARES.
I CAN TAKE CARE OF THAT.
MIKE, IF YOU CAN GET THE GIRLS
HERE FOR CHRISTMAS MORNING,
IT WOULD BE THE MOST AMAZING
CHRISTMAS GIFT EVER,
AND YOU CAN PUT THE BLAME
ALL ON ME.
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
I'LL BE THE GRINCH.
I'LL JUST TELL EVERYBODY
THAT MY HEART
GREW THREE SIZES TODAY.
AND IT MIGHT HAVE HAPPENED,
ACTUALLY.
I GOT THESE WEIRD PAINS
IN MY SHOULDER.
I'M GONNA GET
SOME MORE LIGHTS.
ALL RIGHT.
♪ PA RUM PA PUM PUM
HEY, GIRLS, WOULD YOU COME
DOWN HERE A MINUTE, PLEASE?
WELL, WELL, WELL.
OOH!
WOW. HOW LONG YOU BEEN
STANDING THERE?
LONG ENOUGH, MY FRIEND.
SO, NOW YOU WANT EVERYONE
TO CANCEL THEIR PLANS.
I SUPPOSE I COULD BE
PERSUADED... FOR A PRICE.
NO MORE BLACKMAIL.
GIRLS, GET DOWN HERE!
BUT YOU'RE HONORING
OUR EXISTING DEAL, CORRECT?
JUST GET YOUR GRADES UP,
BANANA HANDS.
WHAT'S GOING ON, DAD?
SIT DOWN, PLEASE.
FAMILY MEETING.
THIS IS GONNA BE BAD NEWS,
BUT I WANT TO DOWNSIZE
YOUR CHRISTMASES.
I DON'T WANT ANYBODY
TRAVELING THIS CHRISTMAS.
(flatly) BUT, HONEY,
THEY ALL MADE PLANS.
LISTEN, I THOUGHT IT WAS OKAY
TO BE WITHOUT YOU GUYS.
TRUTH IS, I DON'T WANT YOU
GONE OVER CHRISTMAS,
'CAUSE WITHOUT YOU GUYS HERE,
IT'S JUST TUESDAY
WITHOUT MAIL DELIVERY.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU'RE DOING THIS, DAD.
I KNOW--
I ALREADY BOUGHT
MY TICKETS...
I CAN--
(singsongy)
AND THEY'RE REFUNDABLE!
(normal voice) WHOO!
OKAY, THERE IS NO GOOD WAY
TO GET TO WINNIPEG,
AND--AND THEN ONCE
YOU'RE THERE, IT'S 23 BELOW.
AND YOU'RE
IN FREAKIN' WINNIPEG.
YEAH. I NEVER WANTED TO GO
WITH THE GOLDSTEINS.
AND, DAD,
COULD I PLEASE HAVE
MY WRAPPING JOB BACK
AT OUTDOOR MAN?
SURE.
I'M TRYING TO SAVE UP
FOR THAT iPad,
WHICH... I GUESS
I'M NOT GETTING?
YOU NEVER KNOW.
I DO. YOU DON'T.
NOW LOOK,
I KNOW YOU'RE GONNA BE UPSET
ABOUT CANCUN--
(inhales)
IT'S JUST AS WELL, I THINK.
CHLOE AND LESLIE ARE,
LIKE, FIGHTING AGAIN.
I DON'T KNOW, I THINK
I'M DODGING A BULLET.
IT'S MEXICO.
IT'S A HAIL OF BULLETS.
AND BESIDES,
I-I HAVE A WHOLE YEAR
TO USE THE TICKET.
SURE. SURE.
SO MAYBE I'LL JUST, LIKE,
WAIT A FEW MONTHS
UNTIL THE WHOLE, LIKE,
DRUG WAR THING BLOWS OVER.
SO, THIS IS GREAT!
I'M SO EXCITED. AND WE'LL HAVE
A DIFFERENT KIND OF CHRISTMAS,
WHERE EVERYBODY PITCHES IN--
HELP WITH THE WRAPPING...
COOKING. 'CAUSE I WANT YOUR MOM
TO BE THE CHRISTMAS QUEEN.
STOP.
DOESN'T HAVE ANYTHING TO DO
UP UNTIL NEW YEAR'S,
WHICH, AFTER THAT, SHE'LL BE
OUT OF COMMISSION, ANYWAY,
WITH THE...
BUT I WANT TO SEE MOO-MAA
AND POPPY-POP.
YEAH, THAT'S WHAT HE CALLS
RYAN'S PARENTS.
I'M SORRY, BOYD.
NO, W-W-WAIT.
WHY DON'T WE HAVE MOO-MOO
AND POO-POO--
BUT--WH-WHY DON'T WE
HAVE THEM HERE FOR THE HOLIDAYS?
REALLY?!
REALLY?
YEAH. YEAH, YEAH. WHY NOT,
HONEY? JUST FOR A FEW DAYS.
W--
THE MORE, THE MERRIER, RIGHT?
(mouths words)
A-ALL RIGHT, YEAH.
YOU HEARD YOUR MOM.
LAST ONE TO CANCEL THEIR PLANS
IS GONNA HAVE TO SHARE A ROOM
WITH THE OLD CANADIANS.
(speaking at once)
I'M AROUND IF YOU NEED
AIRLINE PLANS CHANGED.
THANK YOU.
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
MMM.
MMM. (laughs)
HOW THEY'LL LIVE TOMORROW.
FOR MORE THAN 116 YEARS,
AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL HAS WORKED
FOR THEIR CLIENTS' FUTURES.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
RETIRE ON THEIR TERMS.
WHEN THEY WANT.
WHERE THEY WANT.
DOING WHAT THEY WANT.
AMERIPRISE.
THE STRENGTH OF A LEADER
IN RETIREMENT PLANNING.
THE HEART OF 10,000 ADVISORS
WORKING WITH YOU ONE-TO-ONE.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
TO TELL REAL PEOPLE ABOUT
OUR NEW 15 UNDER $15 MENU.
OH MY GOODNESS!
OH MY GOSH,
THIS LOOKS AMAZING!
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR NEW MAINE STAYS!
15 ENTREES UNDER $15,
SEAFOOD, CHICKEN AND MORE!
OO! THE TILAPIA
WITH ROASTED VEGETABLES!
I'M ACTUALLY LOOKING AT
THE WOOD GRILLED CHICKEN
WITH PORTOBELLO WINE SAUCE.
THAT PORK CHOP
WAS GREAT!
NO MORE
FAST FOOD FRIDAY'S!
WE'RE GOING TO GO
TO RED LOBSTER.
YEP.
[ Male Announcer ]
COME TRY OUR NEW MENU
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY!
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
SALAD, SANDWICHES, AND MORE.
GET $100 OFF ANY 4G LTE TABLET
WHEN YOU BUY ANY SMARTPHONE.
AND GET A TABLET DATA PLAN
STARTING AT JUST $10/MO.
NO SHARING REQUIRED.
HURRY INTO A Sprint STORE
OR VISIT sprint.com/tabletoffer
TODAY.
OR SNOW ANGEL DAY.
NO "PICK OUT YOUR TREE" DAY
OR "CATCH SNOWFLAKES
ON YOUR TONGUE" DAY.
BUT THERE IS A WAY
TO CELEBRATE ALL THESE DAYS --
WITH PILLSBURY
HOLIDAY FUNFETTI.
[ giggles ]
A PERFECTLY SWEET WAY
TO CELEBRATE MORE EVERY DAY.
get to Sears Super Saturday,
WITH PILLSBURY
HOLIDAY FUNFETTI.
with Friday preview.
Coats are 19.99,
and save even more with pass.
Get ½ Carat Diamond
earrings for $49.99.
Plus, all Craftsman wrench
sets are on sale.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
(chuckles) AND APPARENTLY,
HE WASN'T DEAD, THANK GOODNESS.
JUST STUNNED,
AND--AND REALLY PISSED.
IT WAS TERRIFYING.
I'VE PLAYED ENOUGH "ANGRY BIRDS"
TO KNOW WHAT ONE LOOKS LIKE.
(laughs)
AND THEN HE SHOT UP
OUT OF THE TRUNK
AND SOARED MAJESTICALLY
INTO THE NIGHT SKY.
THAT--THAT EAGLE,
JUST LIKE THE GREAT COUNTRY
HE REPRESENTS,
JUST WHEN YOU THINK
HE'S DOWN,
HE SOARS AGAIN,
HIGHER THAN EVER.
I DON'T KNOW HOW MUCH ALTITUDE
THAT BIRD'S GONNA GET.
THERE WAS A LOT OF BLOOD
IN THAT BAG.
YEAH.
OH, BY THE WAY,
DID YOU EVER FIND
THAT PERFECT GIFT
FOR VANESSA?
(chuckles) YEAH.
I DID YOUR DOG THING.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
MUFFIN'S RIGHT HERE.
NO, I DID IT
WITH THE KIDS.
WHAT?
I MADE IT LOOK LIKE THE KIDS
DISAPPEARED FOR CHRISTMAS.
(lowered voice) AND WHEN
VANESSA CHANGED HER MIND,
I BROUGHT 'EM BACK MAGICALLY.
I LOOKED LIKE A BIG HERO.
YEAH, BUT HOW COULD YOU BE
SO SURE THAT VANESSA
WOULD CHANGE HER MIND
AND WANT EVERYBODY BACK?
(normal voice) WELL, LET'S JUST
SAY THE FIX WAS IN.
I GAVE LITTLE BOYD
HIS CHRISTMAS PRESENT EARLY.