FIRE OUT.
>> I TRIED TO PUT IT OUT WITH
FIRE EXTINGUISHERS, BUT CAUGHT
ON TOO FAST.
IT WAS DEVASTATING.
THERE WAS NOTHING I COULD DO.
IT IGNITED REAL FAST.
>> WE HAVEN'T HAD A VERY GOOD
INSURANCE POLICY BECAUSE OF THE
BUSINESS WE DO FOR THE
SEMICONDUCTOR.
SO THE EMPLOYEES WILL BE COVERED
AS FAR AS LOSS, SALARY, WAGES.
>> Reporter: WHILE CNH
ENTERPRISES MAKES COMPONENTS OUT
OF ALUMINUM USED IN THE
SEMICONDUCTOR INDUSTRY.
TOMORROW THE COMPANY WILL MEET
WITH EMPLOYEES TO TRY TO DISCUSS
HOW TO RESUME OPERATIONS HERE AS
SOON AS POSSIBLE, EITHER HERE OR
AT A VERY NEARBY LOCATION.
THE CAUSE OF THE FIRE AT THE
MOMENT UNKNOWN.
I'VE IN FREMONT, ABC 7 NEWS.
>> THANK YOU.
>> WE WANT TO SHOW YOU MORE
VIDEO OF THE FIRE SENT.
IN.
YOU CAN SEE A APARTMENT COMPLEX
IN THE FOREGROUND.
THOSE PLUMES OF BLACK SMOKE
POURING FROM THE PLANT.
WE POSTED MORE VIDEO AND
PHOTOGRAPHS ALONG WITH VIDEO
TAKEN BY A SKY 7HD ON OUR WEB
SITE.
ABC7NEWS.COM.
>> MORE BREAK HUSBAND, OAKLAND
POLICE INVESTIGATING A HOMICIDE.
A MAN SHOT IN THE MIDDLE OF A
RESIDENT STREET.
83rd AVENUE AND E STREET.
YOU CAN SEE THE POLICE HAVE
CLOSED OFF THAT BLOCK WHILE THEY
TRY TO FIGURE OUT EXACTLY WHAT
HAPPENED.
NO WORD YET ON A MOTIVE OR
POSSIBLE SYSTEMS IN THIS
KILLING.
>>> SHOCK AND ANGUISH FOR THE
FAMILIES OF THOSE BEING CARED
FOR AT THE SONOMA DEVELOPMENTAL
CENTER, IT PROVIDES CARE TO
HUNDREDS OF PATIENTS PATIENTS WH
INTELLECTUAL CHALLENGES.
REGULATORS ARE YANKING THE
FACILITY'S LICENSE.
VIC LEE HAS MORE ON WHY IS THIS
HAPPENING?
>> Reporter: DAN, THE SONOMA
DEVELOPMENTAL CENTER HAD A
TROUBLING HISTORY.
REPORTED ABUSES AND POOR
INVESTIGATIONS BY ITS POLICE
FORCE.
AND NOW THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC
HEALTH HAS MOVED TO SHUT DOWN A
MAJOR PORTION OF THE CENTER.
THE PROGRAM THAT CARES FOR
PATIENTS WITH SEVERE
DISABILITIES WHO AREN'T
BEDRIDDEN BY LIVE ON THE
PREMISES.
>> IF THEY CLOSE US, I MEAN, I
DON'T KNOW WHAT WE'RE GOING TO
DO.
>> Reporter: SHE HEADS THE GROUP
OF FAMILY MEMBERS AND ADVOCATES
OF THOSE BEING TREATED AT THE
SONOMA DEVELOPMENTAL CENTER.
HER AUTISTIC SON, DAN, IS ONE OF
SOME 300 RESIDENTS WITH SEVERE
DISABILITIES.
IF THE SONOMA CENTER IS SHUT
DOWN, SHE WILL HAVE TO FIND
SOMEPLACE ELSE FOR HIM.
>> I DON'T KNOW WHERE THAT'S
GOING TO BE.
I MEAN, THAT'S WHAT'S REALLY
SCARING FAMILIES LIKE ME BECAUSE
THAT'S MY KID.
>> Reporter: MILLER SAYS THE
INSTITUTION WAS MAKING POSITIVE
CHANGES.
THAT'S WHY SHE WAS TRULY
SURPRISED BY THE NEWS.
BUT THAT'S NOT HOW THE STATE
REGULATORS SEE IT.
THE PUBLIC HEALTH DEPARTMENT
WHICH MONITORS THE STATE'S FILE
DEVELOPMENTAL CENTERS CONCLUDED
AFTER YEARS OF NONCOMPLIANCE
THAT PATIENTS AT SONOMA HAVE
BEEN REPEATEDLY PUT AT RISK OF
INJURY, SEXUAL ABUSE, AND EVEN
DEATH.
IN PARTICULAR, THE CENTER'S
INTERNAL POLICE FORCE, OFFICE OF
PROTECTIVE SERVICES HAS BEEN
UNDER FIRE FOR ITS LAX
INVESTIGATIONS.
IN 2006, THE U.S. JUSTICE
DEPARTMENT REVIEW FOUND THE
DEPARTMENT'S INVESTIGATIONS
FAILED TO RECONCILE EVIDENCE
APPROPRIATELY, FAILED TO INCLUDE
INTERVIEWS OF RELEVANT STAFF AND
RESIDENTS, AND FAILED TO
DETERMINE THE CAUSE OF SERIOUS
INCIDENTS.
THE PUBLIC HEALTH DEPARTMENT'S
DECISION TO YANK THE CENTER'S
OPERATING LICENSE COMES AFTER A
SERIES OF REPORTS BY ABC 7 AND
CALIFORNIA WATCH.
THEY INCLUDE AN INCIDENT IN THE
FALL OF LAST YEAR WHERE A DOZEN
PATIENTS AT THE CENTER HAD BEEN
TASERED.
THE OFFICE OF PROTECTIVE
SERVICES DISCOVERED A TASER GUN
IN THE CAR OF STAFF MEMBER WHO
WAS LATER FIRED BUT NEVER
CRIMINALLY CHARGED, NOR WAS
ANYONE ELSE.
DESSERTIFICATION WOULD MEAN THE
LOSS OF TENS OF MILLIONS OF
DOLLARS IN MEDICAID FUNDING FOR
THE PROGRAM AT SONOMA.
FEDERAL FUNDING PAYS FOR MUCH OF
THE $300,000 A YEAR CARE PEREZ
DENT.
KATHLEEN MILLER STILL HAS FAITH
THAT THE CENTER WILL MAKE THE
NECESSARY CHANGES.
>> THAT'S VERY SHOCKING AND VERY
DISTURBING AND I HOPE THAT
THEY'RE GOING TO GIVE US SOME
TIME TO TURN IT AROUND.
>> Reporter: THE SONOMA
DEVELOPMENTAL CENTER WILL APPEAL
THE ORDER AND THAT IT WILL
CONTINUE MAKING CHANGES.
THEY'VE STARTED BY ASKING THE
ASSISTANT CHIEF OF THE CHB TO
TEMPORARILY TAKE OVER THEIR
INTERNAL POLICE FORCE.
SONOMA CENTER CAN STAY OPEN AND
CONTINUE RECEIVING FEDERAL FUNDS
DURING THE APPEALS PROCESS.
ABC 7 NEWS.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> EXTRA SECURITY WILL BE ON
SITE TOMORROW AT TWO SCHOOLS
AFTER A BOMB THREAT FORCED THEM
TO SHUT DOWN.
THREATS SCRAWLED ON A WALL.
IT CLAIMED THERE WAS A BOMB IN A
SCHOOL THAT INCLUDED A THREAT
AGAINST A TEACHER.
LINCOLN ELEMENTARY AND ANOTHER
SCHOOL SCHUTT DOWN FOR THE DAY.
NO BOMB FOUND, BUT FRIGHTENING
FOR STUDENTS AND NEIGHBORS.
>> PRETTY BIG DEAL, BECAUSE,
FIRST OF ALL, THERE WAS A NAME
INVOLVED.
>> IT'S LIKE MASS DISRUPTION.
>> SHERIFF'S DEPUTIES WILL BE AT
BOTH SCHOOLS TOMORROW.
>> IS THAT RIGHT SAY THEY'RE
MAKING SURE THE TEACHER NAMED IN
THE THREAT IS RECEIVING
PROTECTION.
>>> A SAN FRANCISCO POLICE
OFFICER HAS BEEN REASSIGNED AND
AN INVESTIGATION IS UNDERWAY
TONIGHT OVER FACEBOOK POST.
THE OFFICER BEHIND IT, SERGEANT
CARL T BRAGGED ABOUT GOING ON A
DRUNKEN HIGH SPEED JOY RIDE.
HE'S ON DESK DUTY WHILE AN
INTERNAL AFFAIRS INVESTIGATION
GETS UNDERWAY.
THE CHIEF HAD HARSH WORDS FOR
THE OFFICER TODAY.
>> IT'S JUST BEYOND
IRRESPONSIBLE AND DUMB.
I WAS OUT OF TOWN YESTERDAY, SO
MY FIRST ACT TO GET BACK WAS TO
REASSIGN THE SERGEANT OUT OF
PATROL.
NOBODY WITH SUCH POOR JUDGMENT
SHOULD BE AROUND THE YOUNGER
OFFICERS.
>> Reporter: HE HAS BEEN BACKING
AWAY FROM HIS FACEBOOK POST EVER
SINCE.
IN AN INTERVIEW WITH THE SF
WEEKLY, HE SAID IT WAS MEANT TO
BE TONGUE IN CHEEK.
HE NOW FACES SUSPENSION.
>>> ONE OF THE BAY AREA'S
BIGGEST POLITICAL SCANDALS OF
THE YEAR TOOK A MAJOR TURN
TODAY.
NADIA LOCKIER, WIFE OF STATE
TREASURER BILL LOCKIER, DROPPED
HER REQUEST FOR A RESTRAINING
ORDER AGAINST HER FORMER
BOYFRIEND.
DAN WAS THE ONLY REPORTER AT THE
HEARING AND HERE WITH MORE ON
THIS FOR US.
>> Reporter: I'VE BEEN TEXT WITH
THE FORMER BOYFRIEND.
THE STORY IS A METH USE WITH
NADIA AND OF A SEX TAPE FACTORED
INTO HER RESIGNING AS COUNTY
SUPERVISOR AND NOW SHE APPEARS
TO BE DOING WELL IN REHAB, BUT
HE IS IN A VERY DARK PLACE.
NADIA DID NOT COME TO COURT THIS
MORNING.
SHE REMAINS IN A SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA REHAB CENTER NOW 107
DAYS SOBER.
NADIA TEXTED THE I TEAM LAST
MONTH.
I AM LOOKING FORWARD TO THIS
ROAD ON RECOVERY AND A NEW WAY
OF LIFE.
>> HER COUNSELORS HAVE HOPE FOR
HER TO COME OUT OF THIS PROCESS
AND MOVE ON WITH HER LIFE.
SO FROM ALL INDICATIONS, THINGS
ARE GOING WELL.
>> Reporter: HER ATTORNEY ASKED
THE JUDGE TO DELAY HEARING HER
REQUEST FOR A RESTRAINING ORDER
AGAINST FORMER BOYFRIEND STEVE
UNTIL SHE GETS OUT OF REHAB IN
FEBRUARY.
THE SCANDAL BLEW UP TEN MONTHS
AGO AFTER A VIOLENT
CONFRONTATION BETWEEN THE TWO AT
THIS NEWARK MOTEL.
IT LEFT HER WITH SCRAPES AND
DEEP BRUISES.
BUT AUTHORITIES DECLINED TO
PRESS CHARGES.
AFTER SHE PUBLICLY DISCUSSED
THEIR METH USE.
SHE RESIGNED FROM THE BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS AND ENTERED REHAB.
TODAY THE JUDGE SUGGESTED
DROPPING THE ISSUE OF A
RESTRAINING ORDER FOR NOW AND
RESCHEDULING IF NECESSARY WHEN
NADIA RETURNS TO THE BAY AREA.
>> SO THE COURT WOULD TAKE THE
MATTER OFF THE CALENDAR AND IF
WE WANT TO DO REISSUE, WE'LL DO
THAT.
OKAY.
GOOD ENOUGH.
>> WHAT DO YOU THINK THE ODDS
ARE OF YOU COMING BACK?
YOU THINK IT COULD DIE RIGHT
HERE?
>> I THINK IS A GOOD CHANCE THIS
COULD DIE HERE.
NADIA WILL GO THROUGH TREATMENT
AND RECONSIDER HER OPTIONS AND
ONE OF THE OPTIONS WILL BE, OF
COURSE, TO CONTINUE TO PURSUE
THIS.
ANOTHER OPTION MAY BE TO LET
MATTERS LIE THE WAY THEY ARE AND
MOVE ON.
>> Reporter: NADIA'S HUSBAND,
BILL, FILED FOR DIVORCE IN JULY.
BUT IT'S NOW ON HOLD, THAT BILL
AND NADIA ARE WORKING WELL
TOGETHER.
BILL'S PAYING FOR REHAB AND
BRINGING THEIR SON TO SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA REGULARLY TO VISIT
NADIA.
IT'S A MUCH DIFFERENT STORY FOR
STEVE.
THERE IS A WARRANT FOR HIS
ARREST AFTER HE MISSED A COURT
APPEARANCE.
POLICE SAY HE TRIED OSTEAL A
SWEATSHIRT WHILE HIGH ON METH IN
AUGUST.
I TEXTED HIM BEFORE THE HEARING
TODAY, ASKING IF HE WOULD
ATTEND.
HE ANSWERED, NOT FEELING LIKE
GOING TO JAIL AND THEY WOULD
TAKE ME IF I SHOWED.
I CAN'T GET PAST THIS.
THE CONNECTION HER AND I HAD WAS
SO STRONG.
LAST NIGHT I SLEPT ON THE
STREETS AGAIN.
I LOST EVERYTHING BECAUSE OF HER
AND THE LIFE SHE FORCED ME INTO.
THIS HOLE I'M IN IS SO DEEP, I
CAN'T GET OUT OF.
IN THE PAST I COULD PULL MYSELF
TOGETHER.
I CAN'T FIND THAT STRENGTH IN
ME.
IT'S JUST NOT THERE.
WHAT IS THERE INSTEAD IS A
WELCOMING THAT MY END WILL BE
SOON.
I CAN'T LIVE LIKE THIS.
I TRIED TO CALL HIM SEVERAL
TIMES TO SEE IF HE'S OKAY AND
JUST GOT HIS VOICE MAIL.
I'M POSTING SCREEN SHOTS OF
THOSE TEXTS AT ABC7NEWS.COM.
>> BY THE WAY, NADIA IS STILL
FACING DRUG AND CHILD
ENDANGERMENT CHARGES IN SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA, BUT HER LAWYER SAYS
THE CASE MAY BE DROPPED IF SHE
CONTINUES TO DO WELL IN REHAB.
>> ALL RIGHT.
THANKS.
>>> STILL AHEAD, A NEW CAMPAIGN
AIMED AT ENDING DOMESTIC
VIOLENCE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
A FIGHT BEING WAGED IN THE
SHADOW OF THE SHERIFF'S
DEPARTMENT SCANDAL.
>> AND IT'S THE MOTHER OF ALL
HIGH TIDE.
ANOTHER KING TIDE.
TONIGHT YOU CAN HELP DOCUMENT
IT.
>> WE HAVE ANOTHER KING TIDE
COMING TOMORROW MORNING.
IT'S GOING TO BE ANOTHER
FREEZING COLD NIGHT FOR SOME
PARTS OF THE BAY AREA.
I'LL TELL WHERE YOU THE FROST
ADVISORIES ARE.
>> I'M MICHAEL FINNEY, AHEAD ON
7 ON YOUR SIDE, I SHOW YOU WHERE
>>> SAN FRANCISCO MAYOR ED LEE
IS LAUNCHING A DOMESTIC VIOLENCE
AWARENESS CAMPAIGN.
THIS COMES AT THE END OF A YEAR
OF MAJOR PUBLICITY OVER A PUBLIC
OFFICIAL CAUGHT UP IN DOMESTIC
VIOLENCE CHARGES.
ABC 7'S NEWS REPORTER MARK IS IN
THE NEWS.
THAT PUT THE SHERIFF AND THE
MAYOR AT ODDS.
>> Reporter: WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
THE SHERIFF'S DOMESTIC VIOLENCE
CHARGE AND HIS EVENTUAL
MISDEMEANOR PLEA AGREEMENT AND
THEN THE MAYOR'S UNSUCCESSFUL
ATTEMPT TO OUST THE SHERIFF FROM
HIS JOB.
TODAY EVERYONE I TALKED TO
INSISTED THIS ISN'T POLITICAL.
>> WE ARE BOTH AN OUTSPOKEN,
ADVOCATES AND WE SHARE A STRONG
VOICE AGAINST DOMESTIC VIOLENCE.
>> Reporter: MAYOR'S OFFICE WAS
PACKED WITH ADVOCATES FOR
WOMEN'S SHELTERS, POLICE
OFFICERS AND PROSECUTORS AS THE
MAYOR ANNOUNCED HIS NEW PUBLIC
AWARENESS CAMPAIGN.
>> DOMESTIC VIOLENCE GOES UP
DURING THE HOLIDAYS.
THERE IS A LOT OF DEPRESSION
THAT GOES ALONG WITH HOLIDAYS
AND WE UNDERSTAND THAT.
SO PEACE AT HOME IS A CAMPAIGN
TO TRY TO ADDRESS THAT RIGHT
AWAY.
>> Reporter: NOT ATTENDING
TODAY'S LUNCH WAS THE SHERIFF,
OR ANYONE FROM THE SHERIFF'S
DEPARTMENT.
>> WELL, THEY'RE NOT PART OF
THIS PIECE OF LEGISLATION.
>> Reporter: THE MAYOR DENIED
HIS CAMPAIGN WAS AIMED IN ANY
WAY AT THE SHERIFF.
THOUGH HE AND BOARD PRESIDENT
DAVID CURE AND DISTRICT ATTORNEY
HAVE ALL BEEN PART OF THE PUSH
TO GET RID OF THE SHERIFF AFTER
HE BRUISED HIS WIFE'S ARM DURING
AN ARGUMENT LAST NEW YEAR'S EVE.
TODAY DAVID CHIOU AND THE D.A.
BOTH SAID TODAY'S PUSH ISN'T
ABOUT THAT.
>> THIS IS REALLY ABOUT
PROTECTING VICTIMS OF DOMESTIC
VIOLENCE.
>> THE NUMBER OF CALLS TO OUR
HOT LINES INCREASED BY 37%.
>> Reporter: BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS PRESIDENT SAYS THE
DOMESTIC VIOLENCE AWARENESS
CAMPAIGN IS NEEDED BECAUSE THE
NUMBERS ARE GOING THE WRONG WAY.
THIS YEAR THERE HAS BEEN MORE
COVERAGE OF DOMESTIC VIOLENCE
ISSUES BECAUSE OF THE CASE THAN
SAN FRANCISCO EXPERTS SAY
THEY'VE SEEN IN, WELL, MAYBE
FOREVER.
>> CERTAINLY THE MESSAGE HAS
BEEN AMPLIFIED FROM CITY HALL
AND WE'RE GLAD TO SEE IT BECAUSE
WE SEE IT EVERY DAY FOR 30
YEARS.
>> Reporter: WE CAUGHT UP WITH
THE SHERIFF IN FRONT OF THE
WOMEN'S RESOURCE CENTER WHERE HE
WAS TAKING PART IN THE SHERIFF'S
TOY DRIVE AND I ASKED IF THE
MAYOR OR THE D.A. HAD CHANGED
THEIR OPPOSITION TO WORKING WITH
HIM ON THEIR DOMESTIC VIOLENCE
CAMPAIGN.
>> THERE HASN'T BEEN A
CONVERSATION BY THEM, BUT I
CONTINUE TO HAVE DIRECTLY WITH
ME.
BUT I CONTINUE TO REACH OUT TO
THEM.
>> Reporter: THE SHERIFF SAYS HE
ISN'T ABOUT TO RESIGN AND HE
ISN'T PAYING ATTENTION TO NEW
EFFORTS TO HAVE HIM RECALLED.
IN THE NEWS ROOM, MARK MATTHEWS,
ABC 7 NEWS.
>> THANK YOU.
BACK AGAIN TODAY, THE DECEMBER
HIGH TIDE KNOWN AS KING TIDE
SWAMPED COAST LINES.
THESE TIDES OCCUR WHEN THE SUN,
MOON AND EARTH ARE IF ALIGNMENT.
SOME SAY CLIMATE CHANGE WILL
MAKE HIGH WATER EVENTS LIKE
THESE MORE COMMON.
>> OPEN A CONVERSATION IN A WAY
WHERE IT'S NO LONGER POLARIZED,
IT BECOMES A CONVERSATION OF
LOOK, THIS IS WHAT WE HAVE AT
RISK NOW.
HOW CAN WE BUILD OUR
MUNICIPALITIES IN SUCH A WAY
THAT THEY ARE RESILIENT TO SEA
LEVEL LIVES?
>> IN SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA, KING
TIDES NEARLY FLOODED A HOTEL.
ONE MAN NAVIGATED THE WATER WITH
A SURF BOARD.
THE CALIFORNIA KING TIDE
INITIATIVE WANTS YOU TO HELP
DOCUMENT THE CHANGES THE TIDES
ARE MAKE.
YOU CAN FIND OUT MORE ABOUT
THEIR PROJECT ON OUR WEB SITE.
ABC7NEWS.COM AND LOOK UNDER SEE
IT ON TV.
>> FASCINATING PHENOMENON.
WHAT A WEIRD PICTURE THAT IS.
>> YEAH, IT IS.
>> JUST KIND OF WADING THROUGH
IT.
>> EXACTLY.
WE HAVE ANOTHER KING TIDE
TOMORROW MORNING, 11:24, 7 FEET.
A LITTLE LOWER THAN TODAY, BUT
WE STILL COULD SEE SOME FLOODING
CONCERNS TOMORROW MORNING.
WE ALSO HAVE FREEZING COLD
CONDITIONS COMING.
>> OH, YEAH.
>> IN CASE YOU DIDN'T FEEL THE
CHILL.
THIS MORNING TEMPERATURES, 30 TO
44 DEGREES.
CAROL POSTED, SO COLD, FROST ON
THE CARS AND HOUSES THIS
MORNING.
BRRR.
WE'RE HEADED THERE AGAIN.
HIGH DEFINITION EAST BOY CAMERA
LOOKING TOWARD SAN FRANCISCO.
TONIGHT IT IS CLEAR.
WE DO HAVE SOME CLOUDS COMING IN
AHEAD OF THE NEXT STORM.
SO FIRST WE'RE GOING TO DEAL
WITH THE COLD, THEN THE WET.
HERE IS A LOOK AT LIVE DOPPLER
7HD.
WE HAD AN ISOLATED SHOWER
EARLIER.
IT'S NOW GONE.
BUT THIS DOPPLER WILL BE
TRACKING RAIN HEADING INTO
TOMORROW MORNING.
LOOK AT THE TEMPERATURES NOW
AFTER THE HIGHS AND THE LOWS TO
UPPER 50S.
NUMBERS ARE DROPPING FAST.
ALREADY 40 DEGREES IN FAIRFIELD.
44 IN LIVERMORE.
46 IN NAPA.
YOU KNOW WE'RE HEADED INTO
ANOTHER FROSTY NIGHT INLAND.
LIGHT RAIN TOMORROW, BIGGER
STORMS ARE DUE IN NEXT WEEK.
I WANT TO SHOW YOU THE FROST
ADVISORY.
IT GOES INTO EFFECT AT 2:00 A.M.
TOMORROW.
RUNS UNTIL 8 A.M
IT'S REALLY FOR THE EAST BAY AND
SALINAS VALLEY.
PATCHY FOG, COUNT ON FROSTY
WINDSHIELD.
SLIPPERY ON THE SIDEWALKS DUE TO
THE PATCHES OF FROST.
YOU'LL WANT TO BUNDLE UP WHEN
YOU HEAD OUT IN THE MORNING AND
MAKE SURE YOU HAVE YOUR RAIN
GEAR WITH YOU.
HERE IS HOW IT WILL PLAY OUT.
DOWN TO FREEZING IN LIVERMORE,
MORGAN HILL, 33 IN FAIRFIELD N
PRACTICE.
34 IN SANTA ROSA.
33 IN CONCORDE.
36 IN FREMONT.
THE CLOUDS THAT ARE COMING IN
AHEAD OF THE STORM WILL ACTUALLY
HELP TO HOLD THE TEMPERATURES UP
JUST A LITTLE BIT COMPARED TO
LAST NIGHT.
SO KEEP THAT IN MIND.
BUT IT WILL START TO GET WET AS
WE HEAD INTO TOMORROW.
HERE IS A LOOK AT THE SYSTEM FOR
YOUR FRIDAY.
THIS ONE ALSO COMING OUT OF THE
GULF OF ALASKA.
CHANCE OF LIGHT RAIN ON FRIDAY.
CERTAINLY IS GOING TO BE ON THE
COLD SIDE.
SERIES OF STORMS LINING UP OVER
THE NEXT SEVEN DAYS.
YOU WILL NEED THE RAIN GEAR AS
WE HEAD INTO THE NEXT SEVEN DAYS
OFF AND ON.
LET ME START OUR COMPUTER
ANIMATION TOMORROW MORNING.
5:00 A.M, JUST CLOUDS.
AS WE HEAD INTO 8:00  O'CLOCK
HOUR, WE START TO SEE A FEW RAIN
DROPS DEVELOP NEAR THE COAST.
AND THIS IS JUST GOING TO BE
HEADING INTO THE AFTERNOON, A
CHANCE OF A FEW SHOWERS.
NOTICE HERE IT IS NOT THE STORM
OF THE CENTURY.
TENTHS OF AN INCH OR LESS
EXPECTED FOR THIS FIRST SYSTEM.
REALLY LIGHT AMOUNTS FOR THE
WEEKEND AS WELL.
SO HIGHS FOR YOUR FRIDAY,
CHILLY.
THESE LOOK LIKE LOWS, THEY'RE
NOT LOWS.
MID 40S TO THE LOW 50S WITH THE
LIGHT RAIN ACROSS THE BAY AREA.
AROUND THE MONTEREY BAY,
TEMPERATURES TO REMAIN ON THE
CHILLY SIDE AS WELL.
UPPER 40S TO THE MID 50S.
YOU NEED A JACKET AND YOUR RAIN
GEAR FOR YOUR FRIDAY.
TEMPERATURES WILL COME UP
SLIGHTLY FOR THE WEEKEND.
LIGHT RAIN CHANCES.
WET AND WINDY FOR MONDAY.
THAT LOOKS A LITTLE MORE LIKE A
MOIST SYSTEM.
MILDER ONE.
WE'LL HAVE COLD SHOWERS TUESDAY
AND THE 7-DAY FORECAST.
THE STRONGEST OF THE SERIES
RIGHT NOW STILL LOOKS LIKE
WEDNESDAY NIGHT, GOING INTO
THURSDAY.
>> THANKS.
>>> STILL TO COME, A LOOK AT WHY
THERE IS A DISTURBING INCREASE
IN THE NUMBER OF YOUNG PEOPLE
SMOKING.
>> AND THAT'S DESPITE ALL THOSE
ANTISMOKING CAMPAIGNS OUT THERE.
STAY WITH US.
MORE TO
>> OBSERVATION LAND AND SAN
FRANCISCO POLICE DEPARTMENT ARE
TRYING TO TAKE BACK THE STREETS
BY TAKING GUNS OFF OF THEM.
THEY ANNOUNCED COMMUNITY BASED
AND FUNDED GUN BUY BACK PROGRAM
ALSO TAKE PLACE SATURDAY.
ONE IN EACH CITY.
RESIDENTS WILL GET $200 PER
WEAPON WITH A LIMIT OF THREE PER
PERSON.
NO QUESTIONS ASKED.
IT'S CO-SPONSORED BY THE OMEGA
BOYS CLUB AND YOUTH UPRISING.
>> PEOPLE ARE STRUGGLING AND
YOU'RE THINKING ABOUT WHAT DOES
IT MEAN TO NOT HAVE RESOURCES
THIS HOLIDAY SEASON THAT YOU CAN
ACTUALLY MAKE A DIFFERENT CHOICE
IN YOUR LIFE.
YOU CAN ACTUALLY TURN IN YOUR
FIREARM AND WE WILL ACTUALLY
GIVE YOU THE KINDS OF RESOURCES
THAT YOU NEED.
>> OAKLAND, THE PROGRAM WILL
TAKE PLACE AT SAINT BENEDICT'S
CHURCH IN SAN FRANCISCO, IT WILL
BE HELD AT THE OMEGA BOYS CLUB.
AT BOTH, IT'S FROM 10:00 O'CLOCK
IN THE MORNING 'TIL 3 P.M
YOU CAN FIND ALL THIS
INFORMATION ON OUR WEB SIDE OF
THE, ABC7NEWS.COM UNDER SEE IT
ON TV.
>>> STATE HEALTH OFFICIALS ARE
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHY MORE
YOUNG PEOPLE ARE LIGHTING UP
THESE DAYS.
SMOKING TOBACCO AMONG 18 TO
24-YEAR-OLDS IS HIGHEST WHEN
COMPARED TO ALL AGE GROUPS.
YOUNG SMOKERS SAY THEY STARTED
IN HIGH SCHOOL.
A RECENT STUDY SHOWS SMOKING IS
HIGHEST AMONG HIGH SCHOOLERS IN
NEIGHBORHOODS WITH AT LEAST FIVE
STORES THAT SELL TOBACCO.
AT THAT MAKES SENSE.
SOME SAY THEY SMOKE OUT OF
STRESS.
>> JOBS, I HAVE THREE JOBS RIGHT
NOW.
ALL OF THAT WAS KIND OF LIKE A
LOT OF PRESSURE.
>> YOUTH AND YOUNG ADULTS GET
ADDICT TO DO TOBACCO, END UP
SMOKING THEIR ENTIRE LIVES AND
SUFFER THE HEALTH CONSEQUENCES.
>> CALIFORNIA PROJECTS IT SPENDS
MORE THAN $6 BILLION A YEAR
DEALING WITH SMOKING-RELATED
HEALTH CARE COSTS.
NOW AS FAR AS ANTISMOKING
CAMPAIGN GOES, FOR EVERY DOLLAR
THE STATE SPENDS ON THESE, THE
TOBACCO INDUSTRY SPENDS $8 TO
ENCOURAGE SMOKING.
>>> A NEW REPORT FINDS
CALIFORNIA'S POPULATION IS
GROWING AT THE SAME PACE AS LAST
YEAR.
THE DEPARTMENT OF FINANCE PUTS
THE NUMBER OF PEOPLE LIVING HERE
AT 37.8 MILLION.
UP BY 250,000 FROM LAST YEAR.
MOST OF THAT GROWTH CAN BE
ATTRIBUTED TO THE BIRTH RATE.
MORE THAN HALF A MILLION BABIES
WERE BORN TO CALIFORNIA FAMILIES
LAST YEAR, TWICE THE NUMBER OF
PEOPLE WHO DIED.
WE ALSO LOST SOME POPULATION TO
MIGRATION.
14,000 MOVED OUT OF STATE.
WHILE THERE ARE 14,000 MORE
PEOPLE MOVED OUT OF STATE THAN
MOVED IN.
>> INTERESTING.
>> THERE IS A LOT MORE TO COME
TONIGHT ON ABC 7 NEWS.
JUST AHEAD, STORY THAT YOU'LL
SEE ONLY ON ABC 7 NEWS.
A BAY AREA FAMILY REACHES A
SETTLEMENT WITH THE FIREPLACE
INDUSTRY OVER A TRAGEDY THAT
HAPPENED IN THEIR HOME.
>> AND GROWING OPPOSITION ON
CAPITOL HILL.
THE U.N. AMBASSADOR DROPS OUT OF
THE RUNNING FOR A JOB SHE HASN'T
EVEN BEEN NOMINATED FOR.
>> AND SAN FRANCISCO'S CABBIES
FIGHT BACK.
THEY DON'T LIKE THE APPS THEIR
COMPETITORS ARE USING.
THEY'RE WATCHING ONE OF THEIR
OWN.
STAY WITH US.
ABC 7 NEWS
[ Female Announcer ]
MARTINELLI'S GOLD MEDAL
SPARKLING CIDER
IS THE PERFECT CHOICE
FOR HOLIDAY GATHERINGS.
MARTINELLI'S IS NON-ALCOHOLIC,
FESTIVE LIKE CHAMPAGNE,
AND TASTES GREAT!
MARTINELLI'S: SINCE 1868.
>>> CHANGES ARE COMING TO THOSE
MODERN GLASS FRONTED GAS
FIREPLACES THAT MANY PEOPLE HAVE
IN THEIR HOMES, PERHAPS YOU HAVE
ONE.
NEW INDUSTRY STANDARDS ARE BEING
WRITTEN IN THE NEXT FEW WEEKS
WITH THE HOPE OF REDUCING THE
NUMBER OF PEOPLE WHO GET BURNED.
HEATHER IS HERE WITH THOSE
CHANGES.
>> Reporter: DAN, FACING
MOUNTING PRESSURE AND LAWSUITS,
FIREPLACE MANUFACTURERS WILL
START ATTACHING PERMANENT
PROTECTIVE SCREENS ON NEW
FIREPLACES IN 2015.
A SAN FRANCISCO MAN WHOSE BABY
DAUGHTER BURNED HER HANDS ON A
GLASS FIREPLACE FEELS THAT
DOESN'T GO FAR ENOUGH AND DOES
NOTHING TO ADDRESS THE MILLIONS
OF FIREPLACES ALREADY IN USE.
IN 2010, THEN 11 MONTH OLD
SYDNEY HAD TO HAVE SKIN TAKEN
FROM HER THIGH TO REPAIR THIRD
DEGREE BURNS ON HER HANDS.
A YEAR LATER, SHE STILL WAS
WEARING COMPRESSION GLOVES TO
PROTECT HER HANDS AND FACED MORE
SURGERIES AHEAD.
ALL BECAUSE OF THIS, A GLASS
FIREPLACE IN HER HOME.
HER TODDLER BROTHER HAD STARTED
IT WITH A REMOTE DURING THE DAY
WITH A SITTER.
NO ONE REALIZED THAT THE TINY
FLAME WAS HEATING THE SCREEN ALL
DAY LONG.
IN THE SUMMER TIME UNTIL LATE
THAT EVENING WHEN LITTLE SYDNEY
PRESSED HER HANDS AGAIN THE
SCREEN TO STAND UP.
THE FIREPLACE HAD COME WITH AN
INSTRUCTION BOOKLET IN FRENCH.
THEY WISHED THE MANUFACTURER HAD
DONE MORE TO PROTECT THEM.
>> JUST A BIG FAT RED STICKER ON
THE WINDOW THAT SAYS THESE
THINGS GET 500 DEGREES WOULD
HAVE BEEN A GOOD START.
>> THE OTHER THING IS I DIDN'T
KNOW IT WAS ON.
SO I FELT LIKE, YOU KNOW, A RED
LIGHT OR SOMETHING.
>> Reporter: NOW THE
MANUFACTURERS ARE DOING
SOMETHING, ENACTING A VOLUNTARY
STANDARD FOR PERMANENT ATTACHED
SCREENS OR BARRIERS ON ALL NEW
FIREPLACES START NOT GUILTY
2015.
INDUSTRY GROUP STASIS IN THE
PAST SEVERAL YEARS, THERE HAS
BEEN REPORTS OF BURNS INVOLVING
YOUNG CHILDREN AND OTHERS WHO
MAY NOT HAVE BEEN AWARE OF THE
POTENTIAL RISK OF BURNS BY
TOUCHING THE HOT GLASS AND
SURROUNDING PANELS ON
FIREPLACES, INSERTS AND STOVES.
AND THOUGH WE BELIEVE THESE
INCIDENTS ARE FEW AND RARE, EVEN
ONE IS TOO MANY.
ON-LINE INVESTIGATIVE NONPROFIT,
FAIR WARNING, SAYS BETWEEN 1999
AND 2009, 2,000 CHILDREN AGED
FIVE AND UNDER WERE BURNED ON
FIREPLACE GLASS.
>> I THINK THE INDUSTRY WILL
TAKE IT ON.
THERE HAS BEEN AT LEAST ONE
CLASS ACTION LAWSUIT THAT WE
KNOW OF AND I THINK THAT THEY
WILL CHANGE AND THEY WILL
EDUCATE THE PUBLIC.
>> BUT SHE WOULD LIKE TO SEE
MORE.
THE FIREPLACE INDUSTRY DID JUST
LAUNCH A CONSUMER EDUCATION
CAMPAIGN.
YOU CAN FIND A LINK AT OUR WEB
SITE, ABC7NEWS.COM.
THE FAMILY HAS A PERSONAL INJURY
LAWSUIT STILL IN THE WORKS AND
THEY'RE PART OF A CLASS ACTION
WHICH IS ALSO STILL IN PROCESS.
DAN, CAROLYN?
>> HEATHER, THANKS.
>>> WITH HER SUPPORT FADING ON
CAPITOL HILL, SUSAN RICE TOOK
HERSELF OUT OF THE RUNNING TO BE
THE NEXT SECRETARY OF STATE.
RICE HAD BEEN CONSIDERED ONE OF
THE FRONT RUNNERS FOR THE JOB TO
BE VACATED NEXT YEAR BY HILLARY
CLINTON.
BUT RICE HAS COME UNDER FIRE FOR
CITING FAULTY INTELLIGENCE ON
THE ATTACK IN BENGHAZI, LIBYA,
IN WHICH CAN A BAY AREA DIPLOMAT
WAS KILLED, ALONG WITH THREE
OTHERS.
ALTHOUGH SHE WAS NEVER FORM LEAL
NOMINATED FOR THE JOB, RICE
SUBMITTED A LETTER TO PRESIDENT
OBAMA TODAY PREDICTING THAT THE
CONFIRMATION PROCESS WOULD BE
LENGTHY, DISRUPTIVE AND COSTLY.
THE PRESIDENT ISSUED A STATEMENT
ACCEPTING RICE'S DECISION, BUT
NOTED THE UNFAIR AND MISLEADING
ATTACKS LEVELED AGAINST HER.
A SPOKESMAN FOR SENATOR JOHN
MCCAIN, ONE OF HER LEADING
CRITIC, SAID HE WOULD CONTINUE
TO SEEK ALL THE FACTS
SURROUNDING THE ATTACK ON THE
CONSULATE IN BENGHAZI.
RICE'S WITHDRAWAL GIVES
MASSACHUSETTS SENATOR JOHN KERRY
THE INSIDE TRACK ON THE
SECRETARY OF STATE JOB.
>>> LET'S FOCUS ON TO ME'S MONEY
MATTERS FOR A HOME OF THE BAY
AREA SOLAR COMPANY SHINES ON
WALL STREET AFTER SLASHING ITS
OFFERING A PRICE IN HALF.
SOLAR CITY OF FOSTER CITY WENT
PUBLIC WITH ITS STOCK TODAY AT
$8 A SHARE.
IT GAINED ALMOST 50%.
SOLAR CITY DON'T MAKE THEM, THIS
INSTALL THEM AND HOPE TO BENEFIT
FROM PLUNGING PRICES.
THE REST OF THE MARKET WENT THE
OPPOSITE DIRECTION TODAY.
THE DOW JONES INDUSTRIALS LOST
74 POINTS.
NASDAQ FELL 21.
THE S & P 500 CLOSED OFF BY 9.
GENERAL MOTORS ROLLED OUT ITS
2014 PICKUPS TODAY.
THEY HAD MORE -- THEY ARE MORE
REFINED AND HAVE MORE MUSCLE
THAN LAST YEAR.
GM PUT MORE THAN $3 BILLION INTO
DEVELOPING THESE NEW MODELS.
AND HOPE TO CHALLENGE FORD,
WHICH HAS THE NUMBER ONE SELLING
TRUCK.
>>> GOOGLE MAPS ARE BACK ON THE
iPHONE AFTER REPLACING THEM
WITH THEIR OWN MAPS THREE-MONTH
AGO.
APPLE PUT A NEW MAP APP AND IT
BECAME THE NUMBER ONE FREE
DOWNLOAD.
90% GAVE IT A FIVE STAR RATING.
>>> CABBIES ARE FIGHTING BACK,
UPSET ABOUT APPS THAT ARE
PRIVATE CARS TAKING AWAY THEIR
BUSINESS.
SO THEY HAVE LAUNCHED AN
AGGRESSIVE NEW CAMPAIGN OF THEIR
OWN WITH AN APP THAT LET'S YOU
CALL A TAXI TO COME PICK YOU UP.
AS JONATHAN EXPLAINS, WHILE THE
OTHER APPS ARE BUTTING HEADS
WITH GOVERNMENT REGULATORS, THIS
ONE IS WORKING WITH THEM.
>> Reporter: AS HE DRIVES HIS
TAXI THROUGH THE BUMPY STREETS
OF SAN FRANCISCO, A LITTLE SMART
PHONE MOUNTED RIGHT BELOW THE
METER STARTS TO RING.
THE PHONE IS RUNNING A BRAND-NEW
APP CALLED FLY WHEEL.
IF YOU'RE A CUSTOMER, THE APP
LOOKS LIKE THIS.
A MAP OF ALL THE PARTICIPATING
CABS IN THE CITY.
>> YOU PUSH ONE BUTTON, THE ONE
NEAREST TO YOU GETS ASSIGNED TO
YOU.
>> Reporter: THE TECHNOLOGY HAS
BEEN AROUND FOR TWO YEARS.
SOME CAB COMPANIES WERE USING IT
EVEN BEFORE THEY LAUNCHED THEIR
APP FOR CALLING BLACK TOWN CARS.
WITH THE DRIVE OFF, IT'S BEING
REBORN AS FLY WHEEL, COMPLETE
WITH BOLD NEW ADVERTISING AND A
PROMISE TO HELP CABBIES COMPETE
WITH THE BLACK CARS AND THE LIFT
DRIVERS WITH THEIR PINK
MUSTACHE.
>> THEY GET ANYWHERE FROM 20 TO
30% MORE RIDES A DAY BY HAVING
THESE MOBILE APPS ABLE TO ACCESS
THEIR VEHICLES REAL TIME.
>> Reporter: IT'S ALREADY IN
ABOUT A THIRD OF SAN FRANCISCO
TAXIS.
NEXT TO THAT OTHER COMMUNICATION
DEVICE.
>> UHF RADIO.
THERE HASN'T BEEN ADVANCEMENT IN
50 YEARS.
NOW WE HAVE THE POWER OF THIS.
>> Reporter: FLY WHEEL CAN
REPLACE OLDER DISPATCH SYSTEMS
OR IN THIS CASE, WORK ALONGSIDE
THE TWO-WAY RADIO TO GIVE THE
DISPATCHER'S A BIRD'S EYE VIEW
OF WHERE THE DRIVERS ARE:  BY
WORKING WITH DISPATCHERS INSTEAD
OF GOING AROUND THEM, THEY
MANAGED TO GET BROAD SUPPORT
PROSECUTE CAB COMPANYIES.
WHILE LIFT, OBVIOUSER AND SIDE
CAR BATTLE FINES FROM STATE
INVESTIGATOR, FLY WHEEL EARNED A
GLOWING ENDORSEMENT FROM THE
CITY.
>> THIS COMPANY WORKED WITH US
AND IT'S SOMETHING WE WILL
RECOMMEND.
>> THE MTA SAYS IT PLANS TO GET
ALL CAB COMPANIES USING LOCATION
TRACKING SO FLY WHEEL AND OTHER
APPS LIKE IT CAN HAIL ANY CAB IN
THE CITY.
>>> JUST AHEAD, THE HOBBIT IS
HERE.
>> DEBUTS TOMORROW, BUT OUR DON
SANCHEZ WASN'T ALL THAT THRILLED
ABOUT WHAT HE SAW.
STAY WITH
>>> MUCH ANTICIPATED IN THEATERS
TOMORROW, THE HOBBIT WITH MANY
OF THE SAME PEOPLE WHO BROUGHT
US THE LORD OF THE RINGS.
>> IT'S FILMED IN 3D TECHNOLOGY
THAT'S SUPPOSED TO BE VERY
SHARP.
BUT SOME PEOPLE CLAIMED IT MADE
THEM SICK.
>> DON SANCHEZ LOOKS HEALTHY
AFTER SEEING IT.
JUST NOT SO HAPPY.
>> I'M LOOKING FOR SOMEONE TO
SHARE AN ADVENTURE.
>> BUT BILBO DOES, JOINING A
BAND OF DWARFS.
THESE CHARACTERS ARE ON A
MISSION.
>> THE DWARFS ARE DETERMINED TO
RECLAIM THEIR HOME LAND.
>> FILLED WITH GOLD AND GUARDED
BAY DRAGON.
>> BACK INTO THE WORLD.
>> Reporter: THIS FILM CAN'T
DECIDE IF IT'S ACTION ADVENTURE
DRAMA OR COMEDY.
>> I'M SURROUNDED BY DWARFS.
WHAT ARE THEY DOING HERE?
>> Reporter: IT GOES BIG SCALE
ACTION WITH SCARY MONSTERS, THE
DIRECTOR LIKES TO USE A
HELICOPTER A LOT.
IT'S IN 3D, ONE REGULAR AND ONE
AT 48 FRAMES PER SECOND.
THAT'S REALLY BREATH TAKING.
IT'S A PREQUEL TO "LORD OF THE
RINGS."
A SMALLER BOOK, BUT IT'S A
TRILOGY ON FILM AND THAT'S WHY
SCENES GO ON SO LONG.
EVENTUALLY THERE IS QUITE A RIDE
AHEAD.
>> HOMES NOW BEHIND YOU.
THE WORLD IS AHEAD.
>> Reporter: LET'S GET BACK TO
THE TECHNOLOGY.
48 FRAMES PER SECOND, DOUBLE THE
REGULAR SPEED.
THE PICTURE IS LIKE A HIGH DEF
SCREEN, UNLIKE ANYTHING YOU'VE
SEEN BEFORE.
I WAS SO FOCUSED ON THE QUALITY
OF THAT PICTURE, I WAS IGNORING
SOP OF THE STORY WHICH WAS EASY
TO DO BECAUSE THERE WERE TIMES
THAT I WAS LOOKING AT MY WATCH
TO SEE HOW LONG IT WOULD LAST.
AND THIS IS A THREE-HOUR FILM.
YEAH, THERE IS SOME VISUALLY
SPECTACULAR SCENES, BUT THE FILM
SEEMS TO HAVE NO HEART.
I WILL GIVE IT A LITTLE BIT MORE
THAN A HALF A BUCKET.
I'M DON SANCHEZ, ABC 7 NEWS AND
WE'LL SEE YOU.
>> NO HEART.
COMING UP NEXT, HOLIDAY SHOPPING
FROM 7 ON YOUR SIDE.
>> MICHAEL FINNEY HAS A LOOK AT
25 WEB SITES WITH COOL GIFTS YOU
CAN BUY FOR UNDER $25.
STAY WITH
>>> THE BAY AREA HOUSING MARKET
CONTINUES ITS MARCH TOWARD
NORMALCY.
THAT'S HOW THE REAL ESTATE
INFORMATION SERVICE DATA TRACK
DESCRIBES NOVEMBER HOME SALES.
FIGURES OUT TODAY.
7300 HOMES WERE SOLD IN THE BAY
AREA LAST MONTH.
THAT'S UP 15.5% FROM LAST
NOVEMBER.
THE MEDIAN PRICE OF A $438,000
HOME NOW IS UP 20% FROM LAST
YEAR.
ACCORDING TO DATA QUICK, HIGHER
END HOMES ARE SELLING BETTER.
FORECLOSURE SALES ARE LOWER THAN
THAN FIVE YEARS.
SOME PEOPLE ARE STILL HAVING
TROUBLE GETTING LOANS, BUT LOW
INTEREST RATES ARE HELPING TO
MAKE UP FOR THAT TO SOME DEGREE.
>>> IF YOU'RE LIKE MOST OF US,
YOU'RE PROBABLY STILL LOOKING
FOR SOME UNIQUE GIFTS FOR THE
HOLIDAYS.
>> ANY GIFTS.
TONIGHT, MICHAEL FINNEY IS HERE
TO SHOW US WHERE TO FIND STUFF
THAT'S AFFORDABLE.
>> YOU'RE DONE!
FINDING THE RIGHT GIFT.
WE'LL HAVE YOU COVERED HERE.
PART OF ABC 7'S EXCLUSIVE
PARTNERSHIP WITH "CONSUMER
REPORTS," THE PEOPLE AT SHOP
SMART HAVE COMPILED A LIST OF 25
WEB SITES WHERE YOU CAN FIND
COOL GIFTS FOR LESS THAN $25.
TONIGHT OUR FIRST STOP IS RIGHT
HERE IN THE BAY AREA.
LINDSAY SULLIVAN IS SHOWING A
LOT OF ORDERS THOSE DAYS TO MEET
THE HOLIDAY RUSH.
THE SAN FRANCISCAN OPERATES SET
BOUTIQUE IN THE BACK ROOM OF HER
HOME JUST OFF RUSSIAN HILL AND
SELLS ONE OF A KIND ITEMS LIKE
THIS TABLET COVER.
>> THESE ARE UNDER $20.
AND THE REALLY INTERESTING THING
IS THAT THEY'RE MADE OUT OF
MITTS BUSHY CAR SEATS.
>> Reporter: THE COVERS WERE
MADE WITH THE EXCESS MATERIAL
THAT MITSUBISHI WOULD HAVE
OTHERWISE THROWN AWAIT A MINUTE
EVERYTHING SHE SELLS, LIKE THESE
RECYCLED GLASS OR $24 EARRINGS
COME FROM MANUFACTURERS THAT ARE
FAIR TRADE CERTIFIED.
>> MY VERY FIRST SPENDERS ARE
ACTUALLY SPENDERS THAT TRAIN
SURVIVORS OF HUMAN TRAFFICKING.
>> Reporter: AT THE TIME ONE OF
25 RETAIL WEB SITES FEATURED
THIS MONTH IN SHOP SMART
MAGAZINE.
>> AND IF YOU SPEND JUST $20,
THEY WILL DONATE $5 TO THE
CHARITY OF YOUR CHOICE.
>> Reporter: EACH WEB SITE
FEATURED OR PRESCREENED BY THEIR
GOOD CUSTOMER SERVICE AND
PRIVACY POLICIES.
THAT INCLUDES ALL-TIME CANDY
WHERE YOU CAN TAKE YOUR SWEET
TOOTH DOWN MEMORY LANE.
>> THEY HAVE RETRO CANDY, ALL
THE FUN STUFF YOU REMEMBER FROM
WHEN YOU WERE A KID, WHETHER
IT'S WAX LIPS OR GUMMY WORMS OR
POP ROCKS FROM THE '70S.
>> Reporter: IF YOU'RE REALLY
STUMPED FOR A GIFT IDEA, CHECK
OUT THAT 19.
YOU'LL FIND NOVELTY ITEMS LIKE A
HAND CRANKED MARSHMALLOW AND HOT
DOG ROASTER FOR 18 BUCKS.
OR ADJUSTABLE MEASURING CUP AND
SPOON FOR ABOUT $13.
IF YOU'RE REALLY BORED, ENENJOY
THE ZANY VIDEOS, LIKE THE
$13 GIANT GUMMY BEAR ON A STICK.
>> IT'S ENOUGH GUMMY BEAR TO
FEED A FAMILY OF SIX.
RESEARCH SHOWS THIS PIECE OF
CANDY TASTES JUST LIKE AN
ORDINARY GUMMY BEAR.
>> Reporter: FINALLY, IF YOU
WOULD RATHER SHOP SOMEWHERE WITH
MORE NAME RECOGNITION, SHOP
SMART LIKES PIERONE.COM.
INDIAN CRAFTED BRACE CANDLE
SNUFFERS.
>> WHAT'S GREAT IS THEY HAVE
UNIQUE THINGS AT VERY LOW PRICE
POINTS.
>> YOU CAN FIND THE COMPLETE
LIST OF WEB SITES FOR COOL GIFTS
UNDER $25 IN THIS MONTH'S ISSUE
OF SHOP SMART.
AND ALSO I LINKED ALL THE SITES
ON ABC7NEWS.COM.
THEY'RE LISTED UNDER 7 ON YOUR
SIDE AND YES, YOU CAN GET A
GIANT GUMMY BEAR ON A STICK.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> I LIKE IT.
I LIKE THE OLD CANDY.
>> THANKS.
>> WE WANT TO THANK YOU FOR MAKE
ABC 7 SHARE YOUR HOLIDAY FOOD
DRIVE SUCH A SUCCESS.
YOU DONATED MORE THAN $22,000 TO
BAY AREA FOOD BANKS YESTERDAY.
THAT TRANSLATES TO FOOD FOR
70,000 PEOPLE.
SHARE YOUR HOLIDAY FOOD DRIVE
CONTINUES THROUGH DECEMBER 31.
YOU CAN DONATE BY CALLING OR
GIVE $10 BY TEXTING FEED TO
80077.
>> SO WE STILL HAVE A WAYS TO GO
HERE.
LET'S UPDATE THE WEATHER
FORECAST AND RAIN COMING BACK.
>> YEAH.
SANDY IS IN FOR SPENCER TONIGHT.
FIRST WE'RE GOING TO FREEZE
TONIGHT AND THEN WE'LL SEE THE
WET WEATHER.
HERE IS A LOOK, RADAR ON MOUNT
SAINT HELENA, NOT TRACKING RAIN
U ABOUT IT WILL BE SOON.
A SYSTEM COMING IN TOMORROW AND
THEN REALLY A SERIES OF SYSTEMS
OVER THE NEXT SEVEN DAYS.
I WANT TO SHOW YOU A COMPUTER
ANIMATION.
A CHANCE AS WE HEAD INTO
TOMORROW MORNING.
AND INTO THE AFTERNOON.
SO VERY LIGHT RAIN WITH THIS
FIRST SYSTEM.
THE SECOND ONE IS OVER THE
WEEKEND.
THAT WILL PRODUCE LIGHT RAIN.
SNOW FOR THE SIERRA NEVADA WITH
THAT SYSTEM A COLD ONE AGAIN.
THEN A THIRD ONE THAT LOOKS
MILDER AND WETTER FOR YOUR
MONDAY.
THAT IS DEFINITELY GOING TO
PRODUCE SOME BREEZY CONDITIONS
AND THEN ANOTHER SYSTEM WILL
FOLLOW WEDNESDAY AFTERNOON,
EVENING, GOING INTO THURSDAY.
THIS ONE LOOKS LIKE THE
STRONGEST OF THE STORMS.
THAT'S JUST A LOOK AT THE WEEK
AHEAD.
ACCUWEATHER 7 FORECAST, OFF AND
ON SHOWERS FOR THE WEEKEND.
KEEP YOUR UMBRELLAS HANDY.
MORE WET WEATHER MONDAY INTO
TUESDAY.
AND YOU'LL NOTICE WEDNESDAY INTO
THURSDAY.
SO EARLY ARRIVAL OF THE WINTER
CHILL.
AND ALSO THE WET WEATHER.
>> ALL RIGHT.
THANKS.
>>> ON TO SPORTS, BIG MONEY NEWS
IN BASEBALL TODAY.
>> YEAH.
LARRY BEIL IS HERE WITH THAT.
>> THE ANGEL DEAL IS INSANE AND
THE GIANTS, MORE MODEST.
BRINGING BACK A FAMILIAR FACE.
SPORTS COMING UP
>> GOOD EVENING.
A FAN FAVORITE COMING BACK TO
SAN FRANCISCO.
ANDRESS TORRES WILL RETURN TO
THE GIANTS.
HE GETS A ONE YEAR CONTRACT
WORTH $2 MILLION.
A KEY MEMBER OF THE 2010 WORLD
SERIES CHAMPIONSHIP CLUB.
HE WAS TRADED TO THE METS FOR
THIS PAST SEASON FOR ANGEL
PAGAN.
TORRES COULD START IN LEFT
FIELD.
MAYBE THERE IS A PLATOON.
I'M NOT SURE HOW IT WILL WORK
OUT.
GIANTS SKIPPER SAID IT IS GREAT
TO HAVE HIM BACK.
FANS WILL AGREE.
>>> ANGELS MORENO, HE LAUGHS AT
THE FISCAL CLIFF.
THE ANGELS JUST SIGNED JOSH
HAMILTON, FIVE YEARS,
$125 MILLION.
THE 31-YEAR-OLD SLUGGER HIT A
CAREER HIGH 35 HOMERS, 128
RBIs FOR 80077.
HE HAS A HISTORY OF ISSUES,
SUBSTANCE ABUSE PROBLEMS.
HE JOINS A POWER PACK ANGELS
LINE - UP.
>>> HERE IS THE TASK FOR THE
49ERS ON SUNDAY NIGHT IN NEW
ENGLAND.
STOP THE HIGHEST SCORING OFFENSE
IN THE NFL, 36 POINTS PER GAME.
LED BY A FUTURE HALL OF FAME
QUARTERBACK IN TOM BRADY.
PATRIOTS, THAT'S WON SEVEN
STRAIGHT.
STRENGTH VERSUS STRENGTH.
THEY'RE ONLY ALLOWING 14 POINTS
PER CONTEST.
TOM BRADY PICKED APART THE
HOUSTON TEXANS DEFENSE.
BRADY SAYS THE PATRIOTS HAVE TO
PLAY BETTER TO BEAT THE NINERS
SUNDAY NIGHT.
>> THERE IS NO REAL WEAKNESS ON
THIS DEFENSE.
THEY DO EVERYTHING WELL AND YOU
HAVE TO DO EVERYTHING WELL, TOO.
YOU HAVE TO -- THAT'S WHAT
HAPPENS WHEN YOU PLAY A TEAM
THAT IS CAPABLE AS THEY ARE.
THEY'VE HAD A GREAT SEASON AND A
GREAT SEASON LAST YEAR.
DEFENSE IS A HUGE REASON WHY.
>> THE RAIDERS WILL PLAY THEIR
FINAL HOME GAME OF THE SEASON ON
SUNDAY.
THEY HOST THE KANSAS CITY
CHIEFS.
ROOKIE ROD STREETER IS MAKING
MORE AND MORE PLAYS FOR THEM.
AMONG THOSE SURPRISED BY THIS,
THE STREETER HIMSELF.
>> DEEP IN THE MIDDLE!
ROD STREETER!
>> STREETER, REALLY THE LAST
COUPLE GAMES HAS MADE BIG PLAYS
FOR US.
>> ROD STREETER HAS MORE
THANKED.
HE'S AN UNLIKELY RISING STAR
WITH FOUR CATCHES FOR 100 YARDS
AGAINST DENVER AND THREE
RESUSPICIONS FOR 96 AGAINST
CLEVELAND.
THE UNDRAFTED ROOKIE HAS BECOME
CARSON PALMER'S FAVORITE.
>> THIS IS CRAZY FOR ME.
I THOUGHT FOOTBALL WAS OVER FOR
ME AND I WAS LOOKING AT GETTING
A JOB.
AND THEN YOU COME HERE AND THEN
THE GAME IS ON YOUR HANDS AND
IT'S A LOT OF PRESSURE, THEN
AGAIN IT'S NOT.
IT'S WHAT YOU PREPARE FOR.
>> Reporter: ONLY SIX MONTHS
AGO, STREETER WAS PREPARING FOR
LIFE AFTER FOOTBALL.
A LACK LUSTER SENIOR SEASON
PRODUCED ONLY 19 RECEPTIONS.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> FORTUNATE LYRICS THE FOOTBALL
JOBS GODS WERE SMILING ON HIM.
ON A WHIM, HE SPARKED INTEREST
FROM THE RAIDERS.
>> I GAVE IT A SHOT.
MIGHT AS WELL WORK OUT.
HAD A GOOD PRO DAY AND THINGS
TURNED AROUND FROM THERE.
I'M GLAD I GAVE IT A SHOT.
>> NICE STORY.
HIGH SCHOOL BASKETBALL,
ARCHBISHOP SAN JOSE ON NATIONAL
TV.
PRIME TIME ON ESPN AGAINST FORT
BEND TRAVIS FROM TEXAS.
FIVE SECONDS LEFT, THEY'RE TIED
AT 50.
AARON HARRISON OF TRAVIS GOES
FOR THE WIN.
NO.
MISSES.
IN OT, HARRISON MAKES UP FOR IT.
HE HAD 26 POINTS.
THAT WAS THE GAME WINNER THERE.
TRAVIS, VICTORIOUS 56-53.
THIS ABC 7 SPORTS REPORT BROUGHT
TO YOU BY MERCEDES BENZ.
>> THAT'S A LOT OF RECRUITS.
>> OH, SURE.
>> THANKS.
>> JOIN ME TONIGHT AT 9:00
O'CLOCK ON COFFEE TV20.
COMING UP, A MAJOR RETAILER GOES
MONEY BALL.
CAN A MAN WHO HELPS RUN THE
OAKLAND A'S NOW INSPIRE A
WINNING BUSINESS?
>> THEN AT 11, BART HAS YOUR
BACK THIS HOLIDAY SEASON.
PEOPLE YOU'VE NEVER MET ARE
OFFERING A YOU SOME PROTECTION.
IT'S ALL COMING UP AT 9 AND 11
ON ABC 7 NEWS.
>> WE'LL SEE YOU THEN.
BUT THAT IS THIS EDITION OF ABC
7 NEWS AT 6.
>> FOR LARRY BEIL, SPENCER
CHRISTIAN, ALL OF US HERE AT ABC
THIS IS "JEOPARDY!"
INTRODUCING
TODAY'S CONTESTANTS --
A TRAINING SPECIALIST
FROM DALLAS, TEXAS...
...A SOCIAL WORKER
FROM BELLEVUE, WASHINGTON...
...AND OUR RETURNING CHAMPION,
A COMPUTER-CHIP DESIGNER
FROM BERLIN, MASSACHUSETTS...
AND NOW HERE IS
THE HOST OF "JEOPARDY!" --
ALEX TREBEK!
THANK YOU, JOHNNY.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN, WELCOME.
OUR CHAMPION, ALISTAIR BELL,
WAS BORN JUST OUTSIDE
OF LONDON IN ENGLAND
AND IS NOW AN AMERICAN CITIZEN
AND SURPRISED A LOT OF PEOPLE
YESTERDAY ON OUR SHOW
BY HIERICANA.DGE
HOW WILL HE DO TODAY AGAINST
THE J's -- JUDY AND JOHN?
WELCOME ABOARD, YOU TWO.
AND GOOD LUCK TO ALL THREE.
HERE WE GO.
THE JEOP OF AMROUND.
LET'S START FINDING OUT WHAT
YOU KNOW ABOUT THESE SUBJECTS.
A LITTLE BIT
ARDY!  EVERYTHING THERE.