>> WELL, YELLOW...
>> OH, YELLOW'S NICE.
>> TEAL...
>> AND RUSY.
>> AND RUST.
>> RUST--RUST AS THE COLOR
RUST...
>> UH-HUH.
>> THERE'S NOT RUSTY THINGS.
>> BOTH.
>> REALLY?
>> OKAY.
>> WITH...
>> ROOSTER WALLPAPER.
>> OH, MY GOSH.
OKAY, THAT'S UGLY.
THAT'S UGLY, YEAH.
AND HOW MUCH WOULD THAT COST
TO REALLY RENOVATE, ROUGHLY?
>> WELL, I DON'T KNOW,
DEPENDS ON HOW MUCH I WIN.
>> OH, THAT'S A GOOD ANSWER.
ALL RIGHT, SO LET'S SEE
THE MONEY IN YOUR ROUND 1 THEN,
COLLEEN.
OKAY, COMPUTER, PLEASE RANDOMIZE
THE DOLLAR AMOUNTS.
[electronic beeping]
HERE ARE THE CATEGORIES TO YOUR
QUESTIONS.
COMPUTER, PLEASE RANDOMIZE
THE CATEGORIES.
[electronic beeping]
AND NOW THAT EVERYTHING IS ALL
SHUFFLED, ARE YOU READY?
>> I AM READY, MEREDITH.
>> AUDIENCE, ARE YOU READY?
[cheers and applause]
THEN LET'S PLAY MILLIONAIRE.
HERE WE GO, COLLEEN.
THE UK'S NATIONAL PIG
ASSOCIATION HAS WARNED THAT
BECAUSE OF RECENT WIDESPREAD
DROUGHT AND THE HIGH COST
OF FEED, WE WILL SOON BE FACING
A WHAT?
>> I KNOW A LOT OF FRIENDS
WHO ARE MAJOR FANS OF BACON.
AND THEY WILL BE REALLY, REALLY.
"B," FINAL ANSWER.
>> BACON!
IT'S BACON.
BACON, BACON, BACON.
LET'S START YOU OFF.
HOW MUCH MONEY IS BEHIND THIS
QUESTION?
WE'RE GONNA START YOUR BANK
AT $3,000.
13 QUESTIONS AWAY FROM
THE MILLION.
"FINANCIAL STATEMENT" IS YOUR
NEXT CATEGORY.
IN FINANCE LINGO,
A "SANTA CLAUS RALLY" IS A SURGE
IN STOCK PRICES THAT OFTEN
OCCURS AT THE END OF WHAT MONTH?
>> SANTA CLAUS COMES TO YOUR
HOUSE AT THE END OF DECEMBER,
SO I HOPE THIS RALLY SHOWS UP
THEN TOO.
"D," DECEMBER, FINAL ANSWER.
>> YES, IT DOES.
IT'S DECEMBER.
LET'S PUT SOME MORE MONEY
IN THAT BANK OF YOURS.
WE HAVE $3,000 SO FAR, AND NOW
WE'RE GONNA ADD ANOTHER
$7,000, UP TO $10,000.
12 QUESTIONS NOW AWAY FROM
A MILLION.
"POMP YOU UP":
BEFORE INCLUDING A FOOTBALL
GAME, THE NEW YEAR FESTIVITIES
IN PASADENA FEATURED
A PROCESSION OF DECORATED
CARRIAGES CALLED THE "BATTLE OF"
WHAT?
>> WELL, PASADENA IS KNOWN FOR
THE ROSE BOWL.
SO I AM NOT CERTAIN OF THIS,
BUT I REALLY HOPE IT IS "A,"
FLOWERS, FINAL ANSWER.
>> IT'S FLOWERS.
>> YES.
>> IT BECAME THE TOURNAMENT
OF ROSES PARADE.
OKAY, LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT
THE MONEY BEHIND THIS QUESTION.
COMPUTER, PLEASE SHOW US
THE MONEY--$2,000.
YOU'RE UP TO $12,000.
STILL IN ROUND 1, 7 QUESTIONS
LEFT IN THIS ROUND.
>> [sighs]
>> "STEVE KNOWS BEST."
WHAT 2012 FILM BASED ON
A STEVE HARVEY BOOK DOLES OUT
SEX AND DATING ADVICE SUCH AS,
"KEEP THE COOKIE IN THE COOKIE
JAR" FOR 90 DAYS?
>> HMM.
>> I AM--I'VE SEEN STEVE HARVEY
PROMOTING HIS BOOK ON TV.
AND I REALLY...
I REALLY THINK...
IT'S "A," THINK LIKE A MAN,
MEREDITH.
[scattered cheers and applause]
FINAL ANSWER.
[chuckles]
>> IT IS THINK LIKE A MAN.
>> WHOO!
[cheers and applause]
AH.
>> "KEEP THE COOKIE IN
THE COOKIE JAR" MEANS NO SEX
BEFORE 90 DAYS.
PRETTY GOOD ADVICE THERE.
LET'S SEE HOW MUCH MONEY IS
BEHIND THIS QUESTION.
$5,000.
I'M GLAD YOU WENT FOR IT.
THAT MEANS YOU HAVE $17,000
IN YOUR BANK.
"COLOR COMMENTARY" IS YOUR NEXT
CATEGORY.
ACCORDING TO
THE HARVARD BUSINESS REVIEW,
SOMEONE WITH "THE MIND OF
THE WHITE-COLLAR WORKER" AND
"THE HANDS OF THE BLUE-COLLAR
EMPLOYEE" IS WHAT KIND OF
WORKER?
>> HMM.
WELL, THIS PERSON SOUNDS LIKE
A GOOD WORKER TO ME IN GENERAL.
BUT I HAVE NO IDEA.
WHITE AND BLUE.
I THINK I'M GONNA HAVE TO JUMP
THE QUESTION, MEREDITH.
>> NO PROBLEM.
THE QUESTION'S OUT OF PLAY.
YOU DO NOT HAVE TO ANSWER IT,
COLLEEN.
CORRECT ANSWER--
GOLD-COLLAR WORKER
IS THE CORRECT ANSWER.
LET'S SEE WHAT YOU JUMPED OVER.
HOPEFULLY, IT'S NOT ONE OF
THE BIG AMOUNTS, BUT WE'LL FIND
OUT.
>> HOPEFULLY NOT.
>> AH.
>> THAT'S FINE.
>> THAT'S NOT A BAD ONE TO JUMP.
OKAY, IT COST YOU $100 BUT KEPT
YOU IN THE GAME.
YOU'RE NOW 9 AWAY FROM
THE MILLION.
"WHY, YOU..." IS THE CATEGORY.
IN THE CLASSIC NINTENDO GAME
DUCK HUNT, WHAT TYPE OF ANIMAL
SMUGLY GIGGLES AND HECKLES
THE PLAYER IF THEY MISS ON ALL
3 SHOTS?
>> YOU KNOW WHAT?
THIS LOOKS LIKE A REALLY SMART
AUDIENCE.
AND I'M GONNA HOPE THAT THERE'S
A LOT OF NINTENDO PLAYERS IN
THIS AUDIENCE.
I'D LIKE TO ASK THE AUDIENCE,
MEREDITH.
>> OKAY, AUDIENCE, COLLEEN NEEDS
YOUR HELP.
ON YOUR KEYPADS, VOTE NOW.
[percussive music]
♪
74% BELIEVE IT IS DOG.
>> THAT'S WHAT I WAS THINKING.
MINE WAS JUST A PURE GUESS.
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT?
WE'RE GONNA GO WITH WHAT
THE AUDIENCE SAYS, "D,"
FINAL ANSWER.
>> WISE DECISION.
IT IS DOG.
LET'S SEE THE MONEY, PLEASE.
HOW ABOUT ANOTHER $1,000,
UP TO $18,000.
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> WE'RE GONNA BE BACK WITH MORE
MILLIONAIRE...
>> THANK YOU.
>> RIGHT AFTER THIS COMMERCIAL
BREAK.
>> WHOO!
[cheers and applause]
Don't judge me!
Whatever it takes, get to
Sears Last Minute Gift Sale.
Get 50% off sleepwear for
her, and more with pass.
Save up to 70% off
all diamonds,
and up to 30% off all Small
Kitchen Appliances.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE RHYTHM OF LIFE.
[ whistle blowing ]
WHERE DO YOU HEAR THAT BEAT?
CAMPBELL'S HEALTHY REQUEST SOUP
LETS YOU HEAR IT...
IN YOUR HEART.
[ basketball bouncing ]
HEART HEALTHY.
GREAT TASTE.
MMM...
[ Male Announcer ] SOUNDS GOOD.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
[dramatic musical flourish]
♪
>> AND WELCOME BACK TO
MILLIONAIRE.
WE ARE WITH COLLEEN DOUGHERTY
FROM NEW JERSEY, $18,000 IN
THE BANK, 8 AWAY FROM
$1 MILLION.
YOUR HUSBAND, CHRIS, IS IN
THE AUDIENCE.
NICE TO SEE YOU, CHRIS.
>> HI, MEREDITH.
>> WELCOME TO THE SHOW.
[cheers and applause]
NOW, HOW DID YOU AND YOUR
HUSBAND MEET?
>> WE ARE AN INTERNET DATING
SUCCESS STORY.
>> OH, FANTASTIC.
>> WE ARE.
ALL YOUR LIFE, YOU HEAR PEOPLE
SAY TO YOU, "OH, YOU'LL KNOW.
YOU'LL KNOW WHEN YOU MEET HIM.
YOU'LL KNOW.
YOU'LL KNOW."
AND SO THEN YOU'RE DATING
DIFFERENT PEOPLE, AND YOU'RE
LIKE, "IS THIS KNOWING?
AM I KNOWING RIGHT NOW?
DOES THIS FEEL LIKE KNOWING?
I DON'T KNOW.
IS THIS KNOWING?"
[laughter]
BUT THEY WERE RIGHT.
>> both: YOU KNEW.
>> OH, YEAH.
>> HOW LONG DID IT TAKE YOU
TO KNOW?
>> WITHIN THREE WEEKS.
>> WITHIN THREE WEEKS?
>> THREE WEEKS.
>> REALLY?
>> I HAVE A THING FOR HEIGHT.
HE'S VERY TALL.
I KEPT GOING TILL I FOUND
SOMEBODY REALLY TALL.
[laughter]
>> AND, CHRIS, HOW LONG DID IT
TAKE YOU TO KNOW?
>> THREE WEEKS.
>> THREE WEEKS, OKAY, GOOD
ANSWER, VERY GOOD ANSWER, CHRIS.
>> SEE, HE'S SMART TOO.
>> HE'S VERY SMART.
[laughter]
AND HOW LONG HAVE YOU GUYS
BEEN MARRIED?
>> IT'LL BE THREE YEARS NEXT
MONTH.
>> OH, THAT'S LOVELY.
SO WE'D LIKE TO GIVE YOU
A LITTLE ANNIVERSARY PRESENT
HERE.
>> YEAH.
>> AS I SAID, $18,000 IN YOUR
BANK.
YOU STILL HAVE ONE LIFELINE
LEFT, 4 QUESTIONS REMAINING
IN ROUND 2.
YOU READY TO KEEP PLAYING?
>> I AM DYING TO KEEP PLAYING.
>> THEN LET'S PLAY.
[dramatic musical flourish]
♪
WHAT IS THE NAME OF THE TWITTER
ACCOUNT THAT POINTS OUT IT
COVERS "CONTROVERSIAL THINGS
ABOUT SEX" AND NOT THE PERSON
WHO "FOUGHT FOR TEMPERANCE"?
>> SUSAN ANTHONY FOUGHT FOR
THE RIGHTS OF WOMEN.
I DON'T BELIEVE SHE WAS--
SHE'S NOT KNOWN
FOR THE TEMPERANCE MOVEMENT.
[dramatic music]
♪
SO I'M LEANING TOWARDS ONE
ANSWER.
BUT THAT'S--
THAT WOULD BE A GUESS ALSO.
>> CAN YOU RULE OUT ENOUGH TO BE
ABLE TO PICK THAT GUESS?
>> WELL, I DO NOT THINK IT'S
LYNDON B. JOHNSON.
CECIL B. DEMILLE, NOPE.
HE WAS INVOLVED IN SHOW
BUSINESS.
"B," IDABIWELLS, FINAL ANSWER.
>> IT WAS "C."
SUSANBIANTHONY WAS THE RIGHT
ANSWER.
[audience groaning]
OH, SHOOT, COLLEEN.
I AM SO SORRY.
>> IS WHAT IT IS.
>> IT IS WHAT IT IS.
>> PLEASURE TO MEET YOU.
>> THANKS, MEREDITH.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
[cheers and applause]
AND JOINING ME NOW IS
LISA PALMA-MCSHERRY FROM
STATEN ISLAND, NEW YORK.
[cheers and applause]
PLEASED TO...
>> HI.
>> MEET YOU.
LISA IS A SPECIAL ED TEACHER.DS.
KIDS LOVE YOU.
BUT I WANT TO SHARE SOMETHING
WITH THE AUDIENCE THAT YOU
PROBABLY WOULDN'T SAY YOURSELF.
LISA'S ALSO THE RECIPIENT
OF THE PATRICK DALY AWARD FOR
HER EFFORTS AFTER 9/11.
SHE ACTUALLY CONTACTED FAMILIES.
SHE HELPED THEM.
SHE WOULD TAKE THEIR KIDS
TO THE PARK.
SHE WOULD BRING FOOD TO THESE
FAMILIES, ANYTHING THEY WANTED.
YOU JUST SHOWED SUCH COMPASSION.
YOU DESERVE THE AWARD.
>> THANK YOU.
>> AND YOU DESERVE
THE $1 MILLION FOR WHAT YOU DID.
>> THANK YOU.
[cheers and applause]
>> REALLY, IT'S PEOPLE LIKE YOU
THAT KEPT THE REST OF THE FOLKS
GOING IN THOSE BAD TIMES.
>> JUST DOING WHAT ANYONE WOULD
DO--I DIDN'T THINK ANYTHING WAS
SPECIAL, JUST HELPING PEOPLE.
AND THEN I WAS RECOGNIZED FOR
IT, BUT THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> WELL, WE WANT TO RECOGNIZE
YOU HERE WITH A LOT OF MONEY,
ALL RIGHT?
>> THANK YOU.
>> SO LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT
THE MONEY IN YOUR ROUND 1.
COMPUTER, PLEASE RANDOMIZE
THE DOLLARS AND THE CATEGORIES
TO LISA'S QUESTIONS.
AND NOW THAT EVERYTHING IS ALL
SHUFFLED, AS THEY SAY, ARE YOU
READY?
>> YES.
>> THEN LET'S PLAY MILLIONAIRE.
[dramatic musical flourish]
♪
HERE WE GO, LISA.
WHAT RECREATIONAL SPORT IS OFTEN
DONE FOR THE FIRST TIME WITH
ANOTHER PERSON STRAPPED TO YOUR
BACK?
>> [chuckles]
>> WELL, MY HUSBAND DID DO THIS,
SO, "D," SKYDIVING,
FINAL ANSWER.
>> BRAVE GUY--IT IS SKYDIVING.
LET'S START BUILDING THAT BANK
OF YOURS.
$5,000, THAT'S A GOOD START.
>> REALLY NICE.
>> 13 AWAY FROM THE MILLION.
"LYRICAL LIES" IS YOUR NEXT
CATEGORY.
DESPITE SINGING ABOUT IT
IN THE ROCK ANTHEM
DON'T STOP BELIEVIN',
STEVE PERRY ACKNOWLEDGED IN
A RECENT INTERVIEW THAT WHAT
AREA DOESN'T ACTUALLY EXIST?
>> [sighs]
[mouthing words]
I HAVE A TERRIBLE VOICE,
SO I DON'T WANT TO SING IT
OUT LOUD.
[mumbling indistinctly]
OH, I'M RIGHT AT THE--MM.
I WOULD LIKE TO ASK
THE AUDIENCE, PLEASE.
>> NO PROBLEM.
AUDIENCE, LISA NEEDS YOUR HELP.
ON YOUR KEYPADS, VOTE NOW.
[percussive music]
♪
76% BELIEVE IT IS SOUTH DETROIT.
THAT'S A BIG NUMBER.
>> YES, IT IS.
AND I AM GOING TO GO WITH
THE AUDIENCE, MEREDITH,
"D," FINAL ANSWER.
>> IT IS SOUTH DETROIT.
>> THANK YOU.
>> THE AUDIENCE WAS RIGHT, WHICH
MEANS WE'RE GONNA PUT SOME MORE
MONEY IN YOUR BANK.
LET'S CHECK IT OUT, HOW MUCH IS
BEHIND THIS QUESTION.
$500, OKAY.
>> OKAY, THAT'S GOOD.
>> $5,500.
>> THAT'S VERY GOOD.
>> 2 DOWN, 12 TO GO.
"COLORFUL SLOGANS" IS THE NEXT
CATEGORY.
WHICH OF THESE HOUSEHOLD BRANDS
REGISTERED A TRADEMARK FOR
THE PHRASE "YELLOW AND BLUE MAKE
GREEN"?
>> "REGISTERED A TRADEMARK,
YELLOW AND BLUE MAKE GREEN."
PALMOLIVE IS GREEN.
TIDE CLEANS GREEN.
I DON'T THINK THAT'S IT.
BRAWNY IS THE QUICKER
PICKER-UPPER.
AND GLAD--OKAY, THAT HELPED.
I THINK IT'S THE LITTLE ZIP TIE
WHEN YOU--SSS--WITH GLAD.
"D," FINAL ANSWER.
>> IT IS GLAD.
YOU ARE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
[applause]
YEAH, THEY HAVE YELLOW AND BLUE
HALVES.
THEY LOOK GREEN WHEN YOU STICK
THEM TOGETHER, VERY GOOD.
HOW MUCH MONEY IS BEHIND THIS
QUESTION?
$10,000.
$15,500, LISA'S OFF TO A GREAT
START.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH MORE
MILLIONAIRE RIGHT AFTER THIS.
YAY.
>> OH, THANKS.
[dramatic musical flourish]
♪
>> AND WE ARE BACK WITH
LISA PALMA-MCSHERRY, OUR SPECIAL
ED TEACHER FROM STATEN ISLAND,
NEW YORK.
$15,500 IN YOUR BANK, 11 AWAY
FROM THE MILLION, 2 LIFELINES
STILL UP THERE.
READY TO KEEP PLAYING?
>> YES.
>> THEN LET'S PLAY.
[dramatic musical flourish]
♪
USING HUMOR TO CONNECT WITH
VIEWERS ON SERIOUS HEALTH
ISSUES, CBS CARES ENLISTED
SHARON AND OZZY OSBOURNE TO
LAUNCH THEIR SECOND ANNUAL WHAT?
>> [laughs]
I DID JUST SEE THE COMMERCIAL
FOR THIS, AND IT'S "B,"
FINAL ANSWER.
>> YOU SAW THE RIGHT COMMERCIAL.
IT IS COLONOSCOPY SWEEPSTAKES.
YOU GOT IT.
LET'S SEE THE MONEY.
$100, UP TO $15,600.
6 QUESTIONS LEFT IN ROUND 1,
SOME BIG MONEY STILL UP THERE
AS WELL.
"TINY HEARTS" IS THE CATEGORY.
WHICH OF THESE DR. SEUSS
CHARACTERS IS SAID TO HAVE
A HEART "TWO SIZES TOO SMALL"?
>> [chuckles]
>> EVERY DECEMBER, I READ
THIS STORY TO MY CLASS.
"C," THE GRINCH, FINAL ANSWER.
>> YEAH, THAT GRINCH WAS
THE RIGHT ANSWER,
MEAN OLD GRINCH.
LET'S HOPE THE MONEY IS SIZEABLE
HERE.
$1,000, $16,600,
9 AWAY FROM THE MILLION.
"ALL IN A NAME":
ACCORDING TO THE FDA'S STANDARDS
OF IDENTITY, WHAT FOOD MUST
CONTAIN AT LEAST 10% BUTTERFAT?
>> I'M PRETTY SURE...
[sighs]
"C," ICE CREAM, FINAL ANSWER.
>> MY FAVORITE FOOD,
IT IS ICE CREAM.
YOU GOT IT RIGHT.
[cheers and applause]
LET'S SEE THE MONEY.
SOME BIG MONEY ON THE BOARD,
IS IT HERE?
NOT YET, $2,000.
$18,600, 4 QUESTIONS NOW LEFT
IN ROUND 1.
AND THE BIG MONEY IS STILL UP
THERE.
"ROAD STOP" IS THE NEXT
CATEGORY.
THE WORD "MOTEL" WAS FIRST USED
IN 1925 WHEN A "MOTOR HOTEL" WAS
BUILT HALFWAY BETWEEN WHAT TWO
CITIES?
[dramatic music]
♪
I HAVE AN IDEA, BUT I'M NOT
SURE, SO I'D LIKE TO SKIP THIS,
PLEASE, JUMP THIS QUESTION,
PLEASE.
>> YOU WANT TO JUMP IT?
OKAY, THE QUESTION'S OUT OF
PLAY.
OUT OF CURIOSITY, WHAT WAS YOUR
IDEA?
>> "C."
>> "C," LET'S SEE IF IT WAS "C."
IT WAS NOT.
>> OH, GOOD.
>> IT WAS SAN FRANCISCO
AND LOS ANGELES.
>> GOOD, YES, I AM GLAD I JUMPED
THE QUESTION.
>> I'M GLAD YOU JUMPED IT
AS WELL.
HOPEFULLY, YOU DIDN'T JUMP OVER
$25,000 OR $15,000.
LET'S SEE.
>> IT'S OKAY.
>> $7,000.
>> OKAY.
>> ALL RIGHT?
>> THAT'S OUT OF PLAY,
BUT THE BIG MONEY REMAINS.
AND BY JUMPING THE QUESTION,
YOU'RE NOW JUST 7 AWAY FROM
THE MILLION.
"DARING DIPLOMACY" IS YOUR NEXT
CATEGORY.
KNOWN FOR HIS USE OF NICKNAMES,
PRESIDENT GEORGE W. BUSH
REFERRED TO THE LEADER OF WHAT
COUNTRY AS "POOTIE-POOT"?
[laughter]
POOTIE-POOT.
>> I THINK MY HUSBAND ACTUALLY
MENTIONED THIS IN THE CAR RIDE
HERE.
>> REALLY?
>> YES.
SO IF I--
>> MAYBE HE HAD TO GO POTTY,
AND YOU'RE CONFUSED.
>> NO, SO IF I'M WRONG, IT'LL BE
HIS FAULT.
>> OKAY, OH.
>> OKAY.
SO I'M GOING TO GO WITH "C,"
RUSSIA, FINAL ANSWER.
>> WELL, YOUR HUSBAND MICHAEL'S
IN THE AUDIENCE.
IS THAT RIGHT, MICHAEL?
>> YES, IT IS.
IT IS RUSSIA, FOR PUTIN.
CHECK OUT THE MONEY BEHIND THIS
QUESTION, COMPUTER, PLEASE.
$3,000.
$21,600.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE A SLIGHT BREAK.
WE'LL BE RIGHT B
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH MORE
MILLIONAIRE.
>> OH, MY.
[cheers and applause]
THANK YOU, CURÉL.
CURÉL ULTRA HEALING LOTION
INSTANTLY RELIEVES AND
PREVENTS DRY SKIN.
YOUR SEARCH FOR DRY
SKIN RELIEF IS OVER.
>> HERE'S YOUR QUESTION
OF THE DAY:
STAY TUNED FOR THE ANSWER.
>> THE ANSWER TO THAT QUESTION
WAS FOUR.
[cheers and applause]
AND WELCOME BACK TO MILLIONAIRE.
LISA PALMA-MCSHERRY FROM
NEW YORK, $21,600 IN HER BANK,
2 QUESTIONS LEFT IN ROUND 1.
YOU GET THESE RIGHT, AND YOU CAN
KEEP ALL THE MONEY IN YOUR BANK
AND TAKE A LOOK AT THAT
$100,000 QUESTION,
6 REMAINING IN THE ENTIRE GAME.
YOU STILL HAVE A LIFELINE LEFT.
READY TO KEEP PLAYING?
>> YES.
>> THEN LET'S PLAY.
[dramatic musical flourish]
♪
APPEARING IMMENSE IN THE NIGHT
SKY, A FULL MOON THAT MAKES
A CLOSE ORBIT TO EARTH IS KNOWN
BY WHAT HEROIC NAME?
>> I'M GOING TO GO WITH "A,"
SUPERMOON, FINAL ANSWER.
>> SUPER JOB THERE.
IT IS SUPERMOON.
YOU GOT IT RIGHT.
IT'S WORTH EITHER $25,000 OR
$15,000, EITHER WAY--
>> I'M JUST FINE WITH IT.
>> THAT'S WHAT IT IS...
[wild cheers and applause]
$25,000.6,600.
YOU ARE UP TO $46,600.
HERE'S THE DEAL, LISA.
I WANT YOU TO UNDERSTAND, YOU'VE
GOT 1 QUESTION REMAINING
IN ROUND 1.
WE KNOW IT'S WORTH $15,000.
IF YOU DO NOT KNOW THE ANSWER
TO THIS, YOU CAN JUMP IT.
YOU WILL AUTOMATICALLY SEE
THE $100,000 QUESTION.
[horn blares]
AH.
HOWEVER, THAT SOUND MEANS YOU
WILL NOT SEE IT TODAY, JUST NEXT
TIME.
AND UNTIL THEN, FOLKS, FROM
NEW YORK, EVERYBODY, BYE-BYE.
[cheers and applause]
I have high blood pressure.
And when I get a cold I take
Coricidin HBP.
The number one pharmacist
recommended cold brand
designed for people with high
blood pressure.
Coricidin HBP.
>> CLOSED CAPTIONING
SPONSORED BY:
[ Female Announcer ] A CLASSIC
MEATLOAF RECIPE FROM STOUFFER'S
STARTS WITH GROUND BEEF,
UNIONS, AND PEPPERS
BAKED IN A KETCHUP GLAZE
WITH SAVORY GRAVY
AND MASHED RUSSET POTATOES.
WHAT MAKES STOUFFER'S MEATLOAF
BEST OF ALL?
THAT MOMENT YOU ENJOY IT
AT HOME.
STOUFFER'S. LET'S FIX DINNER.
>> Announcer: TODAY ON "THE
CHEW" --
WITH JUST ONE WEEK TILL THE BIG
DAY, WE'RE HELPING YOU BRAVE THE
WINTER COLD FRONT WITH A COZY
CHRISTMAS.
AND ALL "PRIVATE PRACTICE" STAR
KaDEE STRICKLAND WANTS FOR
CHRISTMAS IS A CHEESY COMFORT
CRAVING.
>>> PLUS, WHAT GETS DAPHNE EVEN
MORE EXCITED ON CHRISTMAS
MORNING THAN HER PRESENTS?
>>> AND THINK YOU'RE DONE
DECORATING?
"CLINTON'S WORKSHOP" IS ADDING A
FEW FINAL TOUCHES TO YOUR
ALREADY FAB PAD.