DRIVEWAY BLOCKED.
NO ONE WAS ALLOWED ON CAMPUS.
-- POLICE SAY IT IS
PRECAUTIONARY AND THEY
ANTICIPATED THREATS.
THIS COMES AS STUDENTS HEAD
BACK CLASS FOR THE FIRST TIME
SINCE THE SANDY HOOK TRAGEDY.
KATIE MARZULLO IS LIVE WITH
NEW DETAILS.
>> Reporter:
>> Reporter: YOU COULD CALL
ADAM LANZA'S MURDER OF HIS
MOTHER OVERKILL HE SHOT HER
FOUR TILES IN THE HEAD SHE WAS
FUND IN HER PAJAMAS IN DEAD.
ADAM WAS DIAGNOSED WITH AS
SPERGERS LOOKING INTO --
ASPERGER'S LOOKING INTO
WHETHER HE WAS CORRECTLY
DIAGNOSED.
AS ONE FUNERAL ENDED ANOTHER
BEGAN.
FAMILIES EXCHANGED CONDOLENCES
AS ONE LEFT AND THE OTHER
ARRIVED.
6-YEAR-OLD JAMES LOVED MATH
AND RECESS.
JAMES SAID HE DIDN'T WANT
PRESENTS FOR CHRISTMAS HE JUST
WANTED MONEY TO BUY HIS
GRANDFATHER A NEW COFFEE MUG.
6-YEAR-OLD JESSICA HORSES AND
WAS ANXIOUSLY AWAITING HER
10th BIRTHDAY WHEN HER PARENTS
SAID SHE COULD HAVE ONE.
>> I CAN COMPREHEND IT.
I WAS WITH MIGRANT CHILDREN
THIS PAST WEEKEND.
MY HEART GOES OUT.
>> Reporter: STUDENTS
CHARLOTTE AND DANIEL AND
TEACHER VICKI SOTO ALSO BEING
BURIED TODAY.
IN THE END 26 FUNERALS FROM
SANDY HOOK.
DISTRICT OFFICIALS REOPENED
ALL SCHOOLS EXCEPT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
OFFICIALS AND VOLUNTEERS ARE
FIXING A VACANT CAMPUS IN
NEIGHBORING MONROE TO LOOK
LIKE SANDY HOOK FOR WHEN THE
STUDENTS GO BACK.
>> AT THE VERY LEAST WE
WANT GIVE THE CHILDREN AN
OPPORTUNITY TO SEE THEIR NEW
SCHOOL AND BECOME AS
COMFORTABLE AS THEY CAN IN
THAT NEW AREA.
>> Reporter: MOVERS
PHOTOGRAPHED SANDY HOOK'S
CLASSES TO RECREATE THEM AS
BEST THEY CAN RIGHT DOWN TO
THE ARTWORK.
STUDENTS WILL BE REUNITED WITH
BAG PACKS AND OTHER PERSONAL
ITEMS LEFT IN THE CHAOS.
SANDY HOOK COULD BE A CRIME
SCENE FOR MONTHS WHERE
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA WENT ON
A KILLING SPREE HE KILLED HIS
MOTHER FIRST THE GUNS WERE
HERS.
SHE TOOK HIM TO A SHOOTING
RANGE AT LEAST ONCE.
>> IT IS AN EXTREMELY POOR
DECISION ON HER PART.
YOU ARE TALKING ABOUT A SORT
OF A PSYCHOLOGICAL SWITCH THAT
I THINK GO TURNED ON FOR HIM
WITH THE ACCESS OF THE WEAPONS
AND THEN THE READY
AVAILABILITY.
>> Reporter: TWO 6-YEAR-OLD
BYS WERE -- BOYS WERE BURIED
YESTERDAY.
THE TO IS CALLING FOR A MOMENT
OF SILENCE AND CHURCH BELLS TO
RING THIS FRIDAY THE TIME OF
THE SHOOTINGS.
>>> GIGANTIC RETIREMENT FUN
FOR CALIFORNIA TEACHERS
DISTANCING ITSELF FROM
UNEXPECTED FINANCIAL
CONNECTION TO THE CONNECTICUT
TRAGEDY.
THE NATION'S SECOND LARGEST
PENSION FUND HAS MORE THAN 750
MILLION DOLLARS INVESTED WITH
CERBERUS, AN EQUITY FIRM THAT
CONTROLS BUSHMASTER MAKER OF
THE RIFLE USED IN THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING THIS IS YOUTUBE VIDEO
SHOWING HOW THE FIREARMS
OPERATE.
THIS MORNING CERBERUS
ANNOUNCED IT WAS DROPPING ITS
INVESTMENT.
>>> DICK'S SPORTING GOODS
SUSPENDING SALES OF CERTAIN
RIFLES IN RESPONSE TO THE
TRAGEDY.
SEVERAL CALIFORNIA LOCATIONS
CLOSEST TO THE BAY AREA IN
MODESTO, WAL-MART HAS PULLED A
BUSHMASTER RIFLE SIMILAR TO
THE ONE USED OFF ITS WEBSITE.
WAL-MART IS THE NATION'S
LARGEST SELLER OF GUNS AND
AMMUNITION.
>>> HOLLYWOOD IS REACTING TO
THE SHOOTING BY CANCELLING THE
PREMIERES -- PREMIERS OF
SEVERAL FILMS.
ACTOR JIMMY FOX WHO STARS IN
THE MOVIE SAYS THE --
JAMIE FOXX WHO STARS IN THE
MOVIE SAYS THE ENTERTAINMENT
INDUSTRY NEEDS TO BEAR SOME
RESPONSIBILITY.
THE PREMIER OF TOP CRUISE'S
MOVIE WAS ALSO POSTPONED
BECAUSE OF THE SHOOTING.
STAY WITH ABC7 NEWS FOR
CONTINUING COVERAGE OF THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL TRAGEDY.
LAURA ANTHONY IS IN
CONNECTICUT AND REPORT LIVE
LATER.
>>> TEMPERATURES ON THEIR WAY
DOWN LATER TODAY OFFICIALS ARE
ISSUING ADVISORY AND WARNING.
>> HOW COLD IS IT GOING TO
GET?
>>> THIS MORNING ANY
INDICATION IT IS GOING TO BE
COLD, FROST AND ISOLATED AREAS
MORE TOMORROW.
THE COLD AIR IS COMING IN NOW,
YOU CAN SEE SCATTERED SHOWERS
ON LIVE DOPPLER, OVER THE
OCEAN WATER WHICH IS ACTUALLY
WARMER THAN LAND NOW THAT'S
WHY WE HAVE THE SHOWERS THERE.
MAINLY GOING TO STAY OVER THE
OCEAN.
FOR TONIGHT, LET'S START IN
THE NORTH BAY WHERE THE GOING
SEASON WILL END FOR A FEW
PLANTS TEMPERATURES DROP TO 25
TO 30° FOR SEVERAL HOURS THICK
FROST NORTH BAY VALLEYS AND
MOUNTAINS FROM 3:00 TO 8:00.
FROST POSSIBLE IN OTHER AREAS
EAST BAY VALLEYS, BAY
SHORELINE, SOUTH BAY, MONTEREY
BAY, CARMEL VALLEY, HOLE
HISSTER VALLEY ALL COULD HAVE
PATCHY FROST, WATCH OUT FOR
FROSTY WINDSHIELDS AND
SLIPPERY SIDEWALKS TOMORROW
MORNING.
UPDATE ON THE BIG RAIN COMING.
>>> FOR THE SECOND TIME IN A
MONTH, SINKHOLE THREATENING A
CONTRA COSTA COUNTY ROAD THIS
TIME IN CLAYTON ON MARSH CREEK
BETWEEN DEER VALLEY AND PINE
LANE.
CREWS ON THE SCENE NOW AS IS
AMY HOLLYFIELD.
IS THE ROAD SHUTDOWN?
>> Reporter: THEY'VE SHUTDOWN
ONE LANE.
HERE'S WHAT THE SITUATION
LOOKS LIKE, THERE'S A HOLE ON
THE SHOULDER OF MARSH CREEK
ROAD OFFICIALS ARE WORRIED IT
COULD SPREAD TO THE ROAD
ITSELF.
A CREW SUPERVISOR SPOTTED IT
WHEN HE GOT OUT OF HIS TRUCK,
HE SAW A CAVITY UNDER THE
ROAD.
THEY DECIDED TO SHUTDOWN ONE
LANE.
NOW THEY ARE WORKING ON A
TEMPORARY SOLUTION INVOLVING
METAL PLATES SO THEY CAN GET
IT REOPENED.
>> RIGHT NOW WE HAVE TRENCH
PLATES COMING STEEL PLATES TO
PLACE OVER THE ROAD, WE ARE
LOOKING AT 20 FEET LONG SO WE
CAN SPAN THE CAVITY.
WE ARE HOPEFUL THAT WOULD
MITIGATE THE IMMEDIATE HAZARD
UNTIL WE HAVE TIME TO GET A
CONTRACTOR ALSO THE WEATHER IS
SUPPOSED TO BE RAINING THROUGH
THIS WEEK IT WOULD NOT BE A
GOOD TIME TO BE EXCAVATING IN
THE RAIN.
>> Reporter: HERE'S A SHOT OF
THOSE METAL PLATES, THEY ARE
HOPING TO HAVE ALL LANES OPEN
BY THIS EVENING'S COMMUTE.
OFFICIALS SAY THE BACK-UP
BECAUSE OF THE SHUTDOWN LANE
HASN'T BEEN TOO BAD OF A DELAY
FOR DRIVERS.
OF COURSE IT IS BETTER TO HAVE
BOTH LANES UP AND RUNNING.
THEY TO HAVE TO DEAL WITH THAT
PIPE THAT FAILED UNDER THE
ROAD THEY THINK IT WAS RUST
AND OLD AGE EVEN THOUGH THEY
DID INSPECT IT IN 2008 AND IT
LOOKED FINE.
IT HAS FAILED, THEY HAVE TO
DEAL WITH THAT.
FIRST THEY WANT GET THROUGH
THE STORMS COMING UP.
THEY ARE WORKING ON THIS
TEMPORARY SOLUTION, FOR NOW.
AMY HOLLYFIELD, ABC7 NEWS.
>>> STILL AHEAD, BRAZEN
ROBBERY IN THE EAST BAY.
THIEVES USED A CAR TO BREAK
INTO A VIDEO GAME STORE AND
WHAT THEY GOT AWAY WITH.
>>> IS THERE A LIGHT AT THE
END FISCAL CLIFF TUNNEL?
NEGOTIATIONS HEATING UP, RIGHT
NOW.
>>> COLORADO POLICE RELEASING
FRIGHTENING DETAILS ABOUT
APPARENT MURDER-SUICIDE THAT
CLAIMED FOUR LIVES NORTH OF
DENVER.
A WOMAN CALL THE SHERIFF'S
OFFICE TO REPORT A SHOOTING
AND WAS SHOT AND KILLED WHILE
SHE WAS ON THE PHONE.
A MAN GRABBED THE PHONE AND
SAID HE WAS GOING TO KILL
HIMSELF THEN THEY HEARD A
SHOT.
OFFICERS FOUND TWO MEN AND TWO
WOMEN HE SEESED IN THE HOME.
THEY HAVE A POSSIBLE MOTIVE
BUT NOT RELEASING IT.
--
>>> CONCORD POLICE
INVESTIGATING A DIFFERENT KIND
OF SMASH AND GRAB ROBBERY AT A
VIDEO GAME FOR THEnkzfÑ] -- THE
THIEVES DRILLED THROUGH
WINDOWS AT THE GAMESTOP STORE.
THIS IS NEW VIDEO OF THE CAR
BEING PULL OUT OF THE STORE.
THE DRIVER STOLE SEVERAL ITEMS,
INCLUDING USED CELL PHONES
THAT INVESTIGATORS MAY BE ABLE
TO USE TO TRACE IT.
THEY THINK THE CAR MAY BE
STOLEN.
STORE EMPLOYEES HAVE BOARDED
UP THE STORE.
>> NEW THIS MORNING IN
PALO ALTO, PORTION OF SAND
HILL ROAD NEAR STANFORD
UNIVERSITY IS CLOSED AFTER
THIS MESS WAS CAUSED BY A
SUSPECTED DRUNK DRIVER.
THE DRIVER HIT A HYDRANT
SENDING WATER EVERYWHERE.
POLICE TWEETED THIS PICTURE.
THE DRIVER IS UNDER ARREST FOR
DUI.
>>> CONTROVERSY OVER NEW
SPORTING GOODS STORE SET TO
OPEN IN LOS GATOS.
>>> WE ARE GOING TO TALK ABOUT
FREEZING TEMPERATURES TONIGHT
AND NOW THE NEXT SYSTEM WILL
WARM US UP.
I'LL TELL YOU WHEN.
>>> FALLOUT FROM THE
CONNECTICUT TRAGEDY IS
TRIGGERING NEW CONTROVERSY
OVER THE OPENING THIS WEEKEND
OF A SPORTING GOODS STORE SOME
ARE UPSET ABOUT THE GUNS THE
STORE WOULD SELL.
TERRY McSWEENEY IS LIVE IN
LOS GATOS.
THE TOPIC TOOK OVER LAST
NIGHT'S TOWN COUNCIL MEETING.
>> Reporter: IT WASN'T EVEN ON
AGENDA DURING THE PUBLIC
COMMENT PERIOD THAT'S ALL
ANYBODY WAS COMMENTING ON.
THE NEW SPORTING GOODS STORE
AT UNIVERSITY AVENUE IN
LOS GATOS STILL GOING TO OPEN
AS PLANNED SATURDAY.
OPPONENTS CAN CLAIM A PARTIAL
VICTORY.
>> I CAN'T SLEEP AT NIGHT NOW
BECAUSE OF WHAT HAPPENED ON
THE EAST COAST.
>> Reporter: SOME RESIDENTS IN
LOS GATOS ARE IMAGINING
SOMETHING LIKE THAT HAPPENING
IN THEIR COMMUNITY IF THE
TEMPLAR SPORTING GOODS STORE
OPENS SATURDAY, AMONG ITS
OFFERINGS, HIGH END CUSTOM
GUNS.
>> I FEEL AS THOUGH, WE SHOULD
HAVE TALKED ABOUT THIS BEFORE
THIS BUSINESS PERMIT WAS
ISSUED.
WE TALK ABOUT EVERYTHING ELSE.
IT SEEMS LIKE THIS WOULD HAVE
BEEN A BIG MOMENT IN TIME THAT
WE COULD HAVE DISCUSSED.
>> Reporter: THE MAYOR --
[ INAUDIBLE ]
THE TOWN MANAGER SAYS
SATURDAY'S GRAND OPENING
CANNOT BE STOPPED BY THE CITY.
>> SECTION OF THE TOWN CODE
THAT REGULATES THIS AREA WAS
LAST AMENDED IN 1987, IT
DIDN'T GIVE THE TOWN ANY
RESTRICTION TO REVIEW OR EVEN
HOLD A PUBLIC HEARING ON A
RETAILER THAT WANT TOSSLE
FIREARMS.
>> Reporter: HALF OF THOSE WHO
SPOKE AT LAST NIGHT'S MEETING
WANT A BAN ON WEAPONS SALES
SUPPORT A CHANGE IN LAW TO
PROVIDE MORE OVERSIGHT OF
STORES THAT DO SELL GUNS.
THE OTHER HALF WERE DIVIDED
BETWEEN THOSE SUPPORTIVE OF
THE NEW STORE.
>> THE GUYS ARE OUTSTANDING
CITIZENS THAT HAVE INVESTED
THEIR WHOLE LIFE HERE AND CARE
ABOUT THEIR COMMUNITY.
>> Reporter: AND THOSE SUPPORT
HEIVE OF THE NEW STORE WITH
CONDITIONS.
>> THAT -- THAT WOULD BE MY
HOPE IF THEY ARE INTO HUNTING
AND FISHING, THEN LET 'EM SELL
HUNTING AND FISHING.
NOBODY SHOOTING DEER WITH AN
AK-15.
>> Reporter: I E-MAILED
TEMPLAR TO GET THEIR COMMENTS
ON LAST NIGHT'S MEETING AND I
HAVEN'T HEARD BACK FROM THEM
YET.
TERRY McSWEENEY, ABC7 NEWS
>> THERE'S OPTIMISM THIS
MORNING THAT WASHINGTON
LAWMAKERS AND THE WHITE HOUSE
ARE CLOSING IN ON A DEAL TO
AVOID GOING OVER THE FISCAL
CLIFF AND TRIGGERING TAX HIKES
FOR NEARLY EVERYONE COME
JANUARY.
KAREN TRAVERS REPORTS ON THE
PRESIDENT'S NEW COMPROMISE AND
THE REPUBLICANS' BACK-UP PLAN.
>> Reporter: NEGOTIATIONS TO
AVOID THE FISCAL CLIFF ARE
HEATING UP.
BOTH SIDES ARE STARTING TO
MAKE CONCESSIONS.
THIS MORNING SPEAKER BOEHNER
BRIEFED REPUBLICAN LAWMAKERS
ON WHERE THINGS STAND.
>> I CONTINUE TO HOPE WE CAN
REACH BROAD AREA AGREEMENT.
>> Reporter: YESTERDAY BOEHNER
MET WITH PRESIDENT OBAMA FOR
ABOUT 45 MINUTES.
LAST NIGHT THE WHITE HOUSE
PRESENTED HIM A NEW OFFER.
THE PROPOSAL INCLUDES 1.2
TRILLION IN TAX INCREASES,
DOWN FROM THE ORIGINAL OFFER
1.6 TRILLION.
EXTENDING THE BUSH TAX CUTS
FOR EVERY AMERICAN EARNING
LESS THAN $400,000 A YEAR
INSTEAD OF $250,000.
>> HIS POSITION IS NOT BASED
ON THE NOTION THAT THESE RATE
HAVE TO GO UP BECAUSE THAT'S
GOOD, IT IS BASED ON THE
NECESSITY OF HAVING ENOUGH
REVENUE AS PART OF THIS
BALANCED PACKAGE.
>> Reporter: THE WHITE HOUSE
PLAN WOULD LIMIT COST OF
LIVING INCREASES FOR SOCIAL
SECURITY RECIPIENTS AND TWO
YEAR EXTENSION ON DEBT
CEILING.
EVEN AS BOEHNER CONTINUES TO
WORK ON A DEAL WITH THE
PRESIDENT, HE'S KEEPING HANDY,
A PLAN B.
TODAY HE SAID THAT PROPOSAL
WOULD EXTENT THE BUSH TAX CUTS
FOR EVERYBODY MAKING LESS THAN
ONE MILLION DOLLARS, BUT
THAT'S IT.
>> I BELIEVE IT IS IMPORTANT
THAT WE PROTECT AS MANY
AMERICAN TAXPAYERS AS WE CAN.
>> Reporter: BOEHNER SAID THE
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT MAY
HAVE CHANGED THE DYNAMICS OF
THE NEGOTIATIONS.
IT IS NOT THE TIME TO PUT
AMERICANS THROUGH MORE STRESS.
KAREN TRAVERS, ABC NEWS,
WASHINGTON.
>>> TONIGHT YOUR PLANTS MIGHT
BE UNDER STRESS FROM THE COLD.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
ALSO YOUR PETS, PLANTS,
PROBABLY NOT PIPES.
MOST OF US ARE PREPARED
DEFINITELY THOSE TWO THINGS TO
CONSIDER AS WE LOOK AT SUNNY
CONDITIONS OVER THE EAST BAY
HILL AND EAST BAY VALLEYS FROM
VOLLMER PEAK BACK TOWARDS
MOUNT DIABLO, FROM EMERYVILLE
TOWARDS SAN FRANCISCO, SOME OF
CLOUDS OVER THE OCEAN, WHERE
LIVE DOPPLER CONTINUES TO PICK
UP CLOUDS AND SHOWERS.
SHOWERS ARE BECOMING LESS
INTENSE AND NUMEROUS LOOKS
LIKE WE WILL ESCAPE TODAY THE
SHOWERS AND BE DRY.
IF YOU ARE ABOUT TO LEAVE
UPPER 40s TO LOW 50s AROUND
HERE.
MID 40s TO NEAR 50 AROUND THE
MONTEREY BAY AND INLAND.
PARTLY CLOUDY TODAY, SHOWERS
STAY OVER THE OCEAN.
FREEZING COLD EVERYWHERE
TONIGHT.
STORMY PATTERN STARTS THURSDAY.
COLD FRONT FROM YESTERDAY
MOVING TO THE SOUTH BRINGING
RAIN TO SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA.
YET STREAM BRINGING IN THE
COLDEST OF THE AIR MASS MORE
SUN TODAY, TEMPERATURES
FALLING SHORT OF YESTERDAY'S
HIGHS.
TOMORROW INTO THURSDAY, MORE
THURSDAY INTO FRIDAY THIS
SYSTEM WILL TAKE TIME COMING
THROUGH MEANS THIS WILL BE
QUICKLY ON ITS HEELS SATURDAY
AND SUNDAY, WARMER CONDITIONS
AND MORE MOISTURE EACH ONE IS
GOING TO RAISE TEMPERATURES SO
THE COLDEST CONDITIONS ARE NOW
IN THE AFTERNOON AND TONIGHT
DURING THE OVERNIGHT HOURS.
WEDNESDAY AT 5:00, YOU CAN SEE
A FEW SPRINKLES, LIGHT RAIN
SONOMA COUNTY COAST.
INTO THE OVERNIGHT HOURS,
PRETTY MUCH IT.
WE WAKE UP THURSDAY MORNING,
THE NORTH BAY DEALING WITH A
LITTLE LIGHT RAIN THE REST OF
US INCREASING CLOUDS AND
TEMPERATURES WON'T BE AS
FROSTY AS TOMORROW MORNING.
THROUGH THE DAY THURSDAY
INCREASING CLOUDS, DOWN TO THE
SOUTH BAY, MOST OF THE RAIN BY
NOON STILL UP IN THE NORTH BAY
ALSO YELLOWS AND ORANGES
STARTING TO SHOW.
MODERATE RAIN SHOWING UP THERE,
THAT'S WHERE GOING TO STAY
THURSDAY AFTERNOON.
THE STEADIER RAIN STARS TO
WORK INTO THE HEART OF THE
BAY.
THE REASON WHY IT IS GOING TO
TAKE SO LONG FOR THE SYSTEM TO
GET TO THE SOUTH IS THE DRY
AIR WHY WE ARE GOING TO BE SO
COLD TONIGHT ALSO UNDER THIS
LAYER OF MOISTURE AND KEEP
FROM IT REACHING THE GROUND.
THURSDAY NIGHT INTO FRIDAY,
STEADIER RAIN MOVES INTO THE
SOUTH BAY ACROSS ALL OF THE
BAY AND STAYS FROM FRIDAY
MIDNIGHT THROUGH THE MORNING
COMMUTE THEN COMES IN WAVES
FRIDAY, SATURDAY, SUNDAY.
ONCE IT STARS RAINING IT COULD
BE A WASH-OUT FOR THE WEEKEND.
RAINFALL TOTALS MOST
IMPRESSIVE IN THE NORTH BAY,
UP TO THREE TO FOUR INCHES
FRIDAY MORNING THE REST OF US
LESS THAN AN INCH.
MORE RAIN FRIDAY AFTERNOON,
SATURDAY AND SUNDAY.
TEMPERATURES WILL JUMP INTO
THE MID AND YOU HAVER 50s NO
CONCERN WITH WINTRY WEATHER --
HERE THAT WILL FALL IN THE
SIERRA, YOU MIGHT WANT TO GET
THERE BEFORE THURSDAY EVENING.
FRIDAY TO SUNDAY ONE OF THOSE
8 TO 9 HOUR TRIPS TRYING TO
GET UP THERE MONDAY OVER.
NEXT TUESDAY FAIRLY SUNNY, MID
50s.
>>> WE HAVE SOMETHING
INTERESTING.
DOES COLOR MATTER WHEN YOU
TALK ABOUT TOYS?
AN EASY BAKE VICTORY.
>> WHAT HAPPEN AFTER A
DETERMINED LITTLE GIRL TOOK ON
A GIANT TOY COMPANY.
AND...
TAKE CARE OF THEM,
YOU KNOW?
I FEEL LIKE WE'VE
COME FULL CIRCLE.
LIKE THAT!
THIS IS HOW
I'LL DO IT.
Sarah:
THERE YOU GO.
IS THE PERFECT CHOICE
FOR HOLIDAY GATHERINGS.
MARTINELLI'S IS NON-ALCOHOLIC,
FESTIVE LIKE CHAMPAGNE,
AND TASTES GREAT!
MARTINELLI'S: SINCE 1868.
>>> COMING UP ON KATIE ACTOR
HUGH JACKMAN.
THEN AT 4, LONG DEBATE ABOUT
SAFETY OF AIRPORT SCREENING
MACHINES WILL BE ANSWERED BY
SCIENCE.
THEN AT 5, ANIMALS USED TO
BRING RELIEF TO FAMILIES
TRAUMATIZE BY -- TRAUMATIZED
BY THE SANDY HOOK SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
>>> BIG SISTER'S MISSION TO
FIND HER LITTLE BROTHER THE
PERFECT GIFT IS PAYING OFF.
>> 13-YEAR-OLD DIDN'T HAVE TO
GO TO THE NORTH POLE SHE WENT
TO YOUTUBE TO MAKE AN APPEAL
FOR HER 4-YEAR-OLD BROTHER
GAVIN AND THE ONE THING HE
WANTS FROM SANTA THIS YEAR.
>> A MORE GENDER NEUTRAL COLOR
FOR THAT EASY BAKE OVEN.
HASBRO WAS LISTENING AND WILL
SOON OFFER A NEW MODEL, SILVER
AND BLACK EASY BAKE OVEN WILL
BE AVAILABLE IN THE FALL OF
NEXT YEAR IT WILL HAVE WIRE
RIMS AND SPINNERS.
>> WE HAVE TO CHECK IN WITH
OUR FRIEND RYAN SCOTT SEE IF
HE WOULD HAVE MINDED A OVEN.
>> HE MAY HAVE USED HIS
SISTERS.
>> MAYBE.
>> GREAT SHEP.
>> FOR ALL OF US HERE AT
ABC7 NEWS THANKS FOR JOINING
US.
WHO WANTS TO BE A MILLIONAIRE
IS NEXT.
>> IF YOU RECEIVE A SMARTPHONE
REMEMBER YOU CAN BE CONNECTED
WITH ABC7 NEWS ALL THE TIMES
THROUGH OUR APPS, ALARM CLOCK
APP, AND --
>> AND OUR ABC7 NEWS APP IS
AVAILABLE FOR ALL THOSE
DEVICES AS WELL AS THE iPAD
DOWNLOAD OUR APP FOR FREE.
[dramatic music]
♪
[cheers and applause]
>> HELLO, EVERYBODY, AND WELCOME
TO MILLIONAIRE.
TODAY'S FIRST CONTESTANT HAS
VERY SPECIFIC PLANS FOR
THE MONEY THAT SHE WINS TODAY.
SHE WANTS TO BUILD A DREAM
KITCHEN.
FROM NORTHFIELD, NEW JERSEY,
PLEASE WELCOME
COLLEEN DOUGHERTY.
HEY, COLLEEN.
[applause]
YOU KNOW, EVERYBODY LIKES THAT
PERFECT KITCHEN.
HOW BAD IS THE ONE THAT YOU'RE
IN RIGHT NOW?