ONES.
WE HAVE THE LATEST ON WHAT IS
BEING CALLED ONE OF THE WORST
SHOOTING TRAGEDY'S IN AMERICA'S
HISTORY.
IT HAS REIGNITED THAT DEBATE.
LIVE IN SANDY HOOK CONNECTICUT.
GOOD MORNING.
>> GOOD MORNING.
EVERY CORNER OF THIS COMMUNITY
IS STILL MOURNING THE LOSS OF
THOSE INNOCENT LIVES.
EVERY WHERE YOU GO PEOPLE ARE
SHAKING.
THE SCHOOLS THEY ARE GOING TO BE
CLOSED TOMORROW FOR MORE DAY OF
GRIEVING.
>> OVERNIGHT THEY HAD VIGILS
EVEN "SATURDAY NIGHT LIVE" PAID
TRIBUTE TO THE VICTIMS.
HE DESCRIBED THE LAST TIME HE
SAW HIS DAUGHTER EMILY.
>> SHE SAID SHE LOVED ME I GAVE
HER A KISS AND I WENT OUT THE
DOOR.
>> EMILY IS ONE OF THE VICTIMS
ALL OF THE CHILDREN 1ST GRADERS
6 OR 7 YEARS OLD.
6 ADULTS WERE ALSO KILLED AMONG
THEM THE SCHOOL PRINCIPAL AND
PSYCHOLOGIST BOTH MARRIED WITH
CHILDREN.
>> THE PRINCIPAL OF THE SCHOOL
WAS RUNNING TOWARD THE SHOOTER
IN ORDER TO PROTECT HER SUE
DENTS AS WAS THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST.
>> THE GRIM DETAILS DEALT THE
GRIEVING COMMUNITY ANOTHER BLOW.
SOME CHILDREN WERE SHOT AS MANY
AS 11 TIMES.
>> THIS PROBABLY IS THE WORST I
HAVE EVER SEEN.
>> WE ARE LEARNING MORE ABOUT
ADAM LANZA THE 22-YEAR-OLD
SHOOTER HEAVILY ARMED AND CODED
IN KEVLAR CAME IN BY BREAKING
THE GLASS.
HE IS A FORMER STUDENT AND HIS
MOTHER WORKED AS A TEACHER'S AID
THERE ACCORDING TO HER AUNT.
>> SHE EVENTUALLY WOUND UP HOME
SCHOOLING HIM BECAUSE SHE
BATTLED IN THE SCHOOL DISTRICT
IN WHAT CAPACITY I AM NOT 100
PERCENT CERTAIN.
>> NO WORDS CAN EXPRESS HOW
HEARTBROKEN WE ARE WE ARE IN A
STATE OF DISBELIEF AND TRYING TO
FIND WHATEVER ANSWERS WE CAN.
FOR THE SURVIVORS THERE'S ONLY
HEARTBREAK AND HAUNT IMAGES.
>> MY TEACHERS SHE SAVED A LIFE
AND SHE ALSO CALLED MR. GUN HER
HUSBAND AND HE CALLED THE
POLICE.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL MEET THE
GRIEVING FAMILIES AND ATTEND A
PRAYER VIGIL.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> THERE IS A STORY OF HEROISM
RISING FROM THE TRAGEDY.
THIS ONE IS THAT OF VICKY SOTO
SHE WAS A SUBSTITUTE TEACHER
FAMILY MEMBERS SPENT AGONIZING
HOURS AFTER THE SHOOTING
WONDERING WHAT HAPPENED TO HER.
THE WAITING GAME TO RECEIVE
WORD.
THEY WERE HUDDLED BEHIND HER IN
THE CLOSET.
THEY REMEMBER THOSE VICTIMS.
THEY ARE LIVE AT SAINT MARY'S
CATHEDRAL WITH MORE ON WHAT IS
BEING DONE THERE.
GOOD MORNING.
>> OO KIERRA WE ARE HAVING
PROBLEMS WITH YOUR SOUND RIGHT
NOW.
WE ARE GOING TO COME BACK TO
YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH TO TALK
ABOUT THE VIGILS AND MEMORIAL
SERVICES HERE IN THE BAY AREA.
THE NEW TOWN SCHOOL SHOOTING IS
EVERY PARENT'S NIGHTMARE EVEN
THOSE WHO DID NOT LOSE ANY
CHILDREN ARE REALING FROM THE
TRAGEDY.
REPORTER SHOWS US HOW THEY ARE
COPING DESPITE SO MANY
UNANSWERED QUESTIONS.
>> IT'S SO SAD HOW QUICKLY ALL
OF THAT CAN BE TAKEN AWAY FROM
YOU IN A HEARTBEAT.
>> BRIGRIEF HAS SETTLED IN FOR
PARENTS.
>> RATHER THAN DO NOTHING LAURA
CAN AT LEAST LAY FLOWERS AND BE
GRATEFUL HER OWN CHILDREN DON'T
SEEM TO UNDERSTAND.
A LUXURY OF THE VERY YOUNG THAT
MOST DON'T HAVE.
A SMALL COMMUNITY THEY KNOW A
VICTIM SOME DIRECTLY.
>> LAST NIGHT WE FELT SOMETHING
UNUSUAL BECAUSE THEY DIDN'T
RESPOND ON THE PHONE CALLS OR
MESSAGES.
>> (INAUDIBLE).
>> TRYING TO COPE AND CONNECT
SIGNS ARE EVERY WHERE IN THE
TOWN CENTER.
THIS ONE MARKED EACH LOST VICTIM
COUNTING UP TO 27 INCLUDING THE
SHOOTER'S MOTHER.
ANOTHER REMINDED IT WASN'T JUST
CHILDREN WHO WERE LOST.
MANDY IVES IS THINKING OF THE
PRINCIPAL.
HER 9-YEAR-OLD SON WAS A STUDENT
OF THE SCHOOL.
>> WE MOVED HERE IN THE MIDDLE
OF THE SCHOOL YEAR.
SHE WAS SO KIND TO MY SON.
>> DAVID'S FIVE-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHTER ALEXIS WENT TO
PRESCHOOL AT THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
>> I AM AFRAID TO EVEN LOOK AT
IT TO RECOGNIZE AND SEE THE
NAMES OF MY LITTLE ONES
PLAYMATES.
>> HE SENT HIS DAUGHTER TO A
DIFFERENT ELEMENTARY SCHOOL A
STROKE OF FATE ON A DAY WHEN
PARENTS LOOK FOR ANSWERS WHERE
THERE ARE NONE.
>> HEART WRENCHING RIGHT NOW.
IT'S NOT EASY TO SWALLOW WHAT'S
GOING ON IN MY BACKYARD.
>> YOUNG LAW NEW TOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>>> AS THIS TRAGEDY UNFOLDS STAY
WITH ABC 7 NEWS FOR CONTINUING
COVERAGE.
YOU CAN RECEIVE URGENT UPDATES
ON YOUR SMART PHONE BY
DOWNLOADING OUR FREE ABC 7 AND
OPTIONS FOR OUR PUSH
NOTIFICATIONS.
>>> LET'S TURN NOW TO OUR
WEATHER WITH OUR METEOROLOGIST
LISA ARGEN.
>> HI CAROLYN.
GOOD MORNING EVERYONE.
YESTERDAY'S LIGHT RAIN FROM A
TENTH TO TWO TENTHS OF AN INCH.
IT WAS COLD.
WARMEST SPOTS ALONG THE COAST
2K50EGS.
IT IS 49 WE HAVE CLOUDY SKIES
WITH A FEW LIGHT SHOWERS IN THE
NORTH BAY.
TEMPERATURES ARE MUCH WARMER
THIS MORNING DUE TO THE CLOUDS
COVER LOW LEVEL MOISTURE.
SO NUMBERS RANGING FROM THE LOW
40s TO ABOUT 50 THIS AFTERNOON.
MORE SHOWERS AROUND.
BUT THE HEAVIER CONCENTRATED
RAIN FROM THE NEXT COLD FRONT
COMES IN LATER ON TONIGHT JUST
IN TIME FOR YOUR MONDAY MORNING
COMMUTE.
WE WILL LOOK FOR EVEN A FEW
BREAKS IN THE CLOUD DECK THROUGH
OUT THE DAY TODAY.
COASTAL HILLS NORTH BAY MORE
SHOWERS LIGHT SHOWERS WE WILL
TALK ABOUT HOW MUCH RAIN WITH
THIS NEXTS  SYSTEM COMING IN
TONIGHT.
>>> MANY PEOPLE'S MINDS ARE ON
THAT SMALL NEW ENGLAND TOWN IN
CONNECTICUT NEW TOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
SO HERE IN THE BAY AREA THERE
ARE VIGILS AND MEMORIAL SERVICES
TO REMEMBER THOSE WHO DIED.
LET'S GO BACK NOW LIVE TO OUR
ABC 7 NEWS REPORTER TIRA CLAPPER
AT ST. MARYS.
THERE ARE GOING TO BE SERVICES
THERE TODAY AS WELL.
>>> THAT IS RIGHT CAROLYN.
THE REGULAR CHURCH SERVICES WILL
PROCEED HERE.
THOSE INNOCENT VICTIMS WILL BE
REMEMBERED.
ALSO INSIDE THE CATHEDRAL
THERE'S A SPECIAL MEMORIAL SET
UP.
>>> OO YOU HEARD A SPECIAL
ARRANGEMENT OF SILENT NIGHT AT
GRACE CATHEDRAL LAST NIGHT.
IT HAD A NEW MEANING DEDICATED.
SO WAS THE ENTIRE THEY WANT TO
CHANNEL THE GRIEF SO MANY ARE
FEELING BUT THEY HAVE DIFFERING
OPINIONS OF WHAT NEXT STEP
SHOULD BE TAKEN.
>> SIMPLE SOLUTION ABOUT GUN
CONTROL NOT ENOUGH.
WE ALSO MUST ASK WHAT IS BEHIND
THE VIOLENCE.
>> WE HAVE TO START WITH SIMPLE
ACTS.
HOW DO YOU RESPOND TO SOMETHING
LIKE THIS?
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
HOW TO HOW TO REACH OUT.
YOU HAVE TO REACH OUT STARTING
ON THE HOME FRONT WITH THE
FAMILIES.
>> AT LAST NIGHT'S LIGHTING THE
FAITH OF THE DECELEBRATED THE
JEWISH LIGHTS THE REMAINING
CONCERT GRACE CATHEDRAL WILL BE
DEDICATED TO THE CONNECTICUT
VICTIMS.
KIRA CLAPPER ABC 7 NEWS.
>>> THERE IS OTHER NEWS THIS
MORNING SAN FRANCISCO POLICE
HAVE DETAINED A MAN AFTER A
DOMESTIC DISPUTE LED TO A
LENGTHY STANDOFF.
WHEN POLICE ARRIVED THEY PACKBA
AWAY THINKING THE MAN MIGHT HAVE
A WEAPON.
NEARBY RESIDENTS WERE EVACUATED
OR TOLD TO SHELTER IN PLACE
UNTIL THE MANSUR RENDERED AROUND
11:00.
POLICE WERE SEARCHING HIS
APARTMENT FOR A WEAPON PAST
MIDNIGHT.
SAN RAF FELL POLICE A MAN WANTED
FOR MURDER IN THE TRANSIT CENTER
SHOOTING.
THIS WEEKEND THEY RELEASED THIS
PICTURE OF 24-YEAR-OLD SUNNY
DEAN.
HE SHOT A 22-YEAR-OLD MAN ON
PLATFORM D AT THE TRANSIT CENTER
ABOUT 1:00 FRIDAY AFTERNOON.
THE 22-YEAR-OLD VICTIM IS IN THE
HOSPITAL HE IS EXPECTED TO
SURVIVE.
HE WAS ON LOCK DOWN AFTER A MAN
FIRED FROM 50 ROUNDS OF THE
DEPARTMENT STORE PARKING LOT.
IT HAPPENED OUTSIDE MACY'S AT
THE UP SCALE FASHION ISLAND MALL
IN.
HE MADE SURE NOTHING DANGEROUS
WAS INSIDE.
NO ONE WAS HURT.
>>> IN THE EFFORT TO AVOID THE
FISCAL CLIFF A TOP REPUBLICAN
OFFERS TO RAISE TAXES ON THE
WEALTHY.
THE VERY WEALTHY.
FINE OUT WHAT HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER HAS IN MIND.
>>> A POWER SHIFT TODAY IN JAPAN
rPEP
>> HE IS RECOVERING THIS MORNING
AFTER A CAR WENT DOWN A RAVINE
IN THE COUNTY.
IT IS A HALF MILE WEST OF
PANORAMIC HIGHWAY.
THE CAR WAS 150 FEETED ACROSS
THE ROAD THE DRIVER WAS ABLE TO
HOIST HIM TO SAFETY.
HE WENT TO THE GENERAL HOSPITAL
SUFFERING HYPOTHERMIA.
THE HIGHWAY WAS CLOSED BETWEEN
FORT ROSS NORTH OF JENNER.
A SERIES OF STORMS HIT THE AREA.
ENGINEERS HAVE DETERMINED THE
WORK IS GOING TO TAKE LONGER
THAN EXPECTED.
EXPERTS AND POLITICAL LEADERS
FROM CONNECTICUT TO TRY TO
ANSWER THE QUESTIONS.
CAN ANY MEASURES BE TAKEN TO
PREVENT MASS SHOOTINGS IN THE
FUTURE.
IT IS A SPECIAL EDITION OF THIS
WEEK THIS MORNING AT 8 RIGHT
HERE ON NBC 7.
>>> EGYPT'S ISLAMISTS ARE
CLAIMING A MAJORITY VOTE ON THE
COUNTRY'S PROPOSED CHARTER.
IT HAS A NARROW MAJORITY IN THE
FIRST ROUND ON A REFERENDUM
BACKED CONSTITUTION.
THE BROTHERHOOD'S ACCOUNT SHOWS
NEARLY 57 PERCENT 26 MILLION
VOTERS MOIR VOTING IS SET TO
TAKE PLACE IN THE COUNTRY'S
REMAINING 25 MILLION VOTERS.
THE EGYPTIAN PRESIDENT HAILS
FROM THE GROUP WHICH ACCURATELY
PREDICTED PAST ELECTION RESULTS.
JAPANESE VOTERS ARE VOTING IN A
GENERAL ELECTION THAT WILL GIVE
THE COUNTRY 7TH PRIME MINISTER
IN YEARS.
THEY WILL BACK THE LIBERAL
DEMOCRATIC PARTY GIVING IT
ANOTHER CHANCE THEY CALL TSUNAMI
POLITICS PLAY A ROLE NEARLY A
YEAR AFTER THAT DISASTER.
THOUSANDS OF JAPANESE ARE STILL
SUFFERING THROUGH A SECOND
WINTER WAITING FOR THEIR HOMES
WAITING TO BE REBUILT.
>>> AS LAWMAKERS AND PRESIDENT
OBAMA GRAPPLE WITH A WAY TO
AVOID THE FISCAL CLIFF A TOP
REPUBLICAN WILL RAISE INCOME
TAXES ON AMERICANS EARNING MORE
THAN A MILLION DOLLARS A YEAR.
THE MOVE BY HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER IS A CONCESSION IN
NEGOTIATIONS WITH THE PRESIDENT
TO AVOID THE FAST APPROACHING
END OF TEMPORARY TAX CUTS.
BUT THE OFFER FALLS FAR SHORT OF
THE PRESIDENT'S DEMANDS FOR AN
INCREASE ON HOUSEHOLDS EARNING
MORE THAN 250,000 DOLLARS.
A MOVE SHOWS A POSSIBLE BREAK
THROUGH IN THE STAND JUF WITH
THE NATION'S HUGE DEBT PROBLEM A
SPOKESMAN SAYS A DEAL NO IT IS
NOT EMINENT.
>>> WELL, IS WET WEATHER
EMINENT?
CAN WE EXPECT MORE?
OUR METEOROLOGIST LISA ARGEN IS
TRACKING THE WEATHER.
>> IT IS LOOKING MORE ACTIVE
TOWARDS THE END OF THE WORKWEEK.
RIGHT NOW LOOKING AT PLENTY OF
CLOUDS OUT THERE.
DUE TO CLOUD COVER TEMPERATURES
ARE MILDER THIS MORNING.
A LITTLE FOG AND A LOOK AT THE
LAST WEEK BEFORE CHRISTMAS.
FIRST DAY OF WINTER.
ALL OF THAT IS COMING UP.
>> SANTA IS PACKING MORE THAN
GIFTS DURING THIS OPPORTUNITY.
LOOK AT THIS THAT HAS SOME
PEOPLE
>> WELCOME BACK EVERYONE.
IT IS 6:20 ON THIS SUNDAY
MORNING.
HOPEFULLY YOU ARE STAYING NICE
AND WARM.
THIS IS A LIVE LOOK FROM OUR
EAST BAY CAM SHOWING YOU FOLKS
ALREADY TRYING TO GET OUT AND
ABOUT.
MAYBE THEY ARE HOPING TO BE THE
FIRST IN LINE FOR HANUKKAH
GIFTS, CHRISTMAS GIFTS, KWANZAA
GIFTS.
I DON'T KNOW.
WILL RAIN DELAY THAT SHOPPING?
>> NOT REALLY.
WE ARE GOING TO HAVE A FEW
BREAKS TODAY.
WE ARE LOOKING AT AN ACTIVE END
OF THE WORKWEEK.
RIGHT NOW CLOUD COVER IN SAN
FRANCISCO KEEPING TEMPERATURES
MUCH MUCH MILDER.
WE ARE AT NEARLY 50 DEGREES THIS
MORNING.
LIGHT RAIN OFF TO THE NORTH IN
SANTA ROSA.
SUN WI
SUNRISE 7:19.
9 HOURS 33 MEN'S OF DAYLIGHT.
AS WE LOOK AT LIVE DOPPLER 7 H.
D. THIS MORNING TALK ABOUT A
LITTLE BIT OF RAIN IN SANTA ROSA
YOU CAN SEE A FEW RETURNS UP
HERE TOWARDS NAPA VERY LIGHT.
THAT WILL BE THE ORDER OF THE
DAY TODAY AS WE ARE IN BETWEEN
OUR NEXT WEATHER SYSTEM THAT
ARRIVES LATE TONIGHT.
SO FEW LIGHT RETURNS HERE.
WE COULD SEE A SHOWER WITH THE
ATMOSPHERE SO MOIST UNDER THE
WARM FRONTAL SECTOR OF THIS NEXT
SYSTEM.
IT SETS THE STAGE FOR WHAT IS
AHEAD A COLDER AIR MASS NOT AS
COLD BEHIND THE FRONT WHEN THE
CLOUDS CLEAR WE GET THE VERY
VERY COLD CONDITIONS.
THAT SHOULD HAPPEN.
43 IN FAIRFIELD IN TEMPERATURES
ANYWHERE FROM 3-14 DEGREES
MILDER THIS MORNING.
HOPEFULLY YOU FEEL IT OUT THERE
AND TAKING THE CHILL OUT OF THE
AIR.
THE FOG IS A BIT OF A PROBLEM.
VISIBILITY REDUCED HALF-MOON
BAY.
3 MILES NEVADO.
CONCORDE SEEING LOW CLOUDS
THERE.
KNOTTED AS COLD A FEW SHOWERS
MAINLY NORTH THIS AFTERNOON.
POSSIBILITY OF LIGHT SHOWER
EVERY WHERE.
OTHERWISE THE NEXT SYSTEM
ARRIVES LATER ON TONIGHT.
HERE'S A LOOK AT SATELLITE RADAR
COMPOSITE.
THE CLOUD COVER THE MOISTURE FOR
THE NORTH.
WE ARE LOOKING AT THIS WARM BAND
OF RAIN THROUGH OUT THE
AFTERNOON HOURS.
THIS WILL BRING IN ANYWHERE FROM
A TENTH TO TRACE AMOUNTS IN THE
SOUTH BAY.
AS WE FAST FORWARD THE COMPUTER
ANIMATION TO 9:00 THIS MORNING
YOU CAN SEE THE WIDESPREAD RAIN
AS WE GET INTO 9, 10:00 YOU CAN
SEE THE RAIN IN THE NORTH BAY.
MORE WIDESPREAD CONCENTRATED
RAIN IN THE OVERNIGHT HOURS.
BY 11, 12:00 TOMORROW WE ARE
INTO THAT BREAK.
WITH A FEW SCATTERED SHOWERS
AFTER THAT THE NICE BREAK COLDER
CONDITIONS WILL LAST TUESDAY
INTO WEDNESDAY.
COLDER OVERNIGHT CONDITIONS.
A FEW SUNNY BREAKS IN THE
AFTERNOON WITH TUESDAY WEDNESDAY
FEATURING THE DRY PERIOD QUARTER
TO HALF AN INCH AND PENINSULA
EAST BAY TRACE AMOUNTS IN THE
SOUTH BAY.
NORTH BAY HALF INCH TO AN INCH
RIGHT ON THROUGH TOMORROW
AFTERNOON.
TEMPERATURES TODAY UPPER 40s
HALF-MOON BAY 50s SAN FRANCISCO.
50s TOWARD THE EAST BAY.
DON'T BE SURPRISED TO SEE A FEW
SUNNY BREAKS.
AFTER THIS NEXT WEAK SYSTEM WE
WILL SEE A FEW SHOWERS TUESDAY
BRIEF BREAK WEDNESDAY AND RAIN
SURES, FRIDAY, SATURDAY LOOKS
LIKE IT COULD SPREAD SEVERAL
INCHES OF RAIN IN THE NORTH BAY.
SO WE WILL BE WATCHING THAT
CLOSELY.
>> ALL RIGHT.
WE HAVE THAT ONE LITTLE DAY TO
KIND OF DRY OUT AND PEOPLE CAN
GET READY FOR BIGGER STUFF
COMING DOWN THE PIKE.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> THANK YOU, LISA.
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL TRAGEDY IS
STIRRING UP THE GUN DEBATE ALL
OVER THE NATION.
ONE TEXAS GUN RANGE IS SMACK IN
THE MIDDLE OF THE CONTROVERSY
AFTER AN UNUSUAL OPPORTUNITY IN
SANTA.
>> SMILE.
>> IT IS CRUHRISTMAS AT THE GUN
RANGE IT MEANS PICTURES WITH
SANTA.
AND HIS AR 15.
>> IT'S A CHILD FRIENDLY EVENT.
>> I THINK IT'S EXTREMELY
IMPORTANT TO TRAIN CHILDREN, TO
EDUCATE THEM, TAKE THE MYSTERY
OUT OF THE GUNS.
>> DON'T TELL THAT TO REVEREND
PETER JOHNSON A STRONG ADVOCATE
OF GUN CONTROL HE SAYS KIDS AND
GUNS SENDS A WRONG MESSAGE.
>> WE HAVE TO TALK ABOUT OUR
LOVE AFFAIR IN EYE LENS.
>> HE THINKS VIOLENCE WOULD
DECREASE IF THEY WERE HARDER TO
GET.
HE TOOK 22,000 GUNS DURING GUN
BUY BACKS.
>> WE AREN'T GOING TO BE ABLE TO
TAKE GUNS OUT OF AMERICA'S HANDS
BUT I THINK WE MUST BEGIN TO
TALK TO AMERICA ABOUT VIOLENCE
ITSELF.
>> THE OWNERS OF THE GUN RANGE
SAY THEY DON'T ADVOCATE
VIOLENCE.
THE NUMEROUS GUN SAFETY CLASSES.
>> THIS IS ONE OF THE REASONS WE
OPENED THE RANGE WAS TO EDUCATE
CHILDREN TO TRAIN THEM IN THE
CORRECT WAY TO USE THEM.
IT CAN BE A FUN SUPPORT DOESN'T
HAVE TO BE DANGEROUS.
>> THE PROBLEM IS THE PERSON
BEHIND THE GUN NOT THE WEAPON
ITSELF.
>>> IF PEOPLE WANT TO HURT
ANOTHER PERSON THEY CAN USE A
BASEBALL BAT.
>> THE DIFFERENCE IS A BASEBALL
BAT IS FOR HITTING THE BASEBALL.
A GUN IS FOR KILLING PEOPLE.
>> BOTH SIDES DIFFER ON WHAT
NEEDS TO BE DONE BOTH SAY THEY
ARE UNITED IN PAIN AND ANGER
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED IN
CONNECTICUT AND BOTH BELIEVE
SOMETHING HAS TO BE DONE SO NO
MORE INNOCENT PEOPLE DIE IN
SCHOOLS.
>>> REBECCA LOW HIS REPORTING.
LET'S CHECK OUT SPORTS.
THE 49 YEARS FACE TOM BRADY AND
THE NEW ENGLAND PATRIOTS WHILE
STATE CHAMPS EMERGE IN HIGH
SCHOOL FOOTBALL.
THE WARRIORS ARE OFF TO THEIR
BEST START IN YEARS.
HERE IS SPORTS.
>> LONGEST ROAD TRIP OF THE YEAR
7 GAMES IN 7 DAYS ENDED
YESTERDAY IN AN LAW A-- ATLANTA.
TOOK A LOSS IN ORLANDO BUT ENDED
WITH A WIN OVER ATLANTA COMING
HOME 6-1.
BEST START SINCE THE 91-92
SEASON.
ROOKIE IMPROVING THE GAME.
THREE OF THE 12 IN THE FIRST
HALF.
HE HAD 19 IN THE GAME.
HE HAD 19 AS WELL.
THIS SETEAM IS MOST EFFECTIVE WN
EVERYONE GETS INVOLVED.
THREE OF HIS 13.
DAVID LEE AT 20 POINTS, 1 POINTS
AVERAGING A DOUBLE DOUBLE 20-10
ON EVERY SINGLE GAME ON THIS
TRIP.
TWO REBOUND SHOTS OF A TRIPLE
DOUBLE.
HE HAD 18 POINTS.
WARRIORS 6-1 ON A ROAD TRIP FOR
THE FIRST TIME IN FRANCHISE
HISTORY.
115-93 THE FINAL.
UC DAVIS NONCONFERENCE MATCH UP
AFTER A COUPLE WEEKS OF EXAMS.
23 OF THE TEAM'S 52 POINTS.
ONLY TWO HIT DOUBLE DIGITS.
THE JUMPER AND THE FOUL.
HE HAD 14 POINTS.
CARDINAL LED 43-29 AT THE HALF.
LED THEM OFF AT 20.
75-52 VICTORY.
>>> 6TH IN THE NATION IN
STORING.
JUSTIN COBBS CARRIED THE LOAD.
HE HAD 18.
NO MATCH FOR DOUG MCDERMOTMCDER.
CAL FALLS 6-3 WITH THE 10 POINT
VICTORY.
>>> THE HIGH SCHOOL FOOTBALL
STATE CHAMPIONSHIP.
CENTENNIAL HAS STATE'S LEADING
OFFENSE WITH TWO 1,000 YARD
RUSHERS.
HE TALKED ABOUT RETIRING AFTER
34 YEARS AT THE HELM.
THREE OF THE FOUR RUSHING YARDS.
THEY WERE UP 21-0.
SECOND HALF QUARTERBACK CHRIS
WILLIAMS GUNS IT TO AUSTIN LONE
STAR.
GREAT NAME.
38 YARDS 39-14 SPARTANS.
CENTENNIAL HAD A GREAT OFFENSE.
COULDN'T GET IT ANY CLOSER.
EXTENDING THE LEAD ONCE AGAIN.
OPEN DIVISION STATE CHAMPIONS
FOR THE 4TH STRAIGHT YEAR.
>>> DIVISION 3 TITLE GAME.
HEADED TO CAL THROUGH FOUR TD'S.
WILDCATS UP.
HE RAN FOR 272 YARDS.
CAN'T COACH SPEED AND THIS KID
HAS SOME.
79 YOORDZ.
MADISON IS THE CIF DIVISION 3
CHAMPION WITH A 38-35 VICTORY.
>> 49ERS IN NEW ENGLAND TO TAKE
ON THE PATRIOTS TONIGHT.
I AM MIKE SHUMANN HAVE A GREAT
DAY.
>>> A JOB SENATOR IN THE EAST
BAY IS THE CENTER OF A
CONTROVERSY.
IT'S A WAY TO HELP DECREASE
VIOLENCE IN OAKLAND SO WHY WOULD
ANY ONE BE AGAINST IT?
THAT STORY AHEAD.
>>> HUNDREDS OF NURSES IN THE
BAY AREA ARE OURSING THE HOLIDAY
SEASON TO SEND A
AND...
TAKE CARE OF THEM,
YOU KNOW?
I FEEL LIKE WE'VE
COME FULL CIRCLE.
LIKE THAT!
THIS IS HOW
I'LL DO IT.
Sarah:
THERE YOU GO.
Oh, did you want it?
Yea
We'll split it.
[ Female Announcer ]
Made fresh, so light,
buttery and flakey.
That's half
That's not half!
Guys, I have more!
Thanks Mom
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Crescents.
Let the Making Begin
[ Female Announcer ]
HOLIDAY COOKIES ARE A BIG JOB.
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE
JUST RIGHT.
PERFECTION IS IN THE DETAILS.
♪
GET TO HOLIDAY FUN FASTER
WITH PILLSBURY COOKIE DOUGH.
>> WELCOME BACK EVERYONE.
VIGILS HONORING THOSE KILLED ARE
BEING HELD AROUND THE NATION
INCLUDING HERE IN THE BAY AREA.
WE ARE OF COURSE TALKING ABOUT
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THERE IS A SERVICE AT SAINT
MARY'S CATHEDRAL THIS MORNING.
GRACE CATHEDRAL BROUGHT TOGETHER
PEOPLE TO SHOW PRAYERS FOR THE
FAMILIES OF THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL TRAGEDY.
ABC 7 NEWS REPORTER SERGIO
CONTANA HAS MORE.
>> OLIVIA ENGEL, BORN JULY 18TH,
2006.
>> AT A CANDLELIGHT VIGIL ON THE
FRONT STEPS OF THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL THE NAMES OF THOSE KILLED
IN CONNECTICUT WERE READ.
>> THESE CHILDREN WERE 5 AND 6
YEARS OLD.
WE ALL KNOW 5 AND 6-YEAR-OLDS
WHICH IS WHY IT WAS SO IMPORTANT
TO GATHER ON THE FRONT STEPS OF
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> AMONG THOSE THE REVEREND
RHODES.
SHE SHARED HER FAMILIAR LACE
PAIN.
HER COUSIN HAD TWO CHILDREN AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY WHO
MANAGED TO ESCAPE SAFELY.
SHE HASN'T BEEN ABLE TO TALK TO
THEM ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED.
>> SHUT THEIR PHONE OFF BUT I AM
GETTING A POST FROM FACEBOOK AND
I WILL PROBABLY TALK TO THEIR
GRANDMOTHER IN THE NEXT COUPLE
OF DAYS.
>> THEY HELD THEIR VIGILS FOR
ABOUT AN HOUR WHICH IS LONGER
THAN THE ORGANIZER SUSPECTED.
>> I WAS SURPRISED MY HUSBAND
COUNTED 49 PEOPLE WHICH RAIN AND
COLD AND JUST FOUND OUT ABOUT IT
A FEW HOURS AGO.
>> ACROSS THE PAY IN SAN
FRANCISCO ANOTHER GROUP BRAVED
THE RAIN AND THE COLD.
CHILDREN HELD SIGNS SPELLING OUT
CALLS FOR ACTION.
THESE VIGILS SPRUNG UP ACROSS
THE BAY ALL HAVE A SIMILAR
THEME.
THEY ARE COMING TOGETHER TO SHOW
SUPPORT OF THE FAMILIES OF THOSE
LOST AND TO CALL FOR CHANGE.
>> WE HAD UNFORTUNATELY A NUMBER
OF SHOCKING SHOOTINGS EVEN
WITHIN THE LAST YEAR.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT TAKES FOR
US TO REACH A TIPPING POINT.
I WILL BE CURIOUS TO SEE IF THIS
IS A TIPPING POINT.
>> ABC 7 NEWS.
>>> UNITED AIRLINES ARE GETTING
A NEW UNION CONTRACT THAT BRINGS
THEM CLOSER TO FINALIZING THE
MERGER WITH CONTINENTAL.
PILOTS WILL GET BIG RAISES
AVERAGING 43.2 PERCENT INCLUDING
LARGER RETIREMENT CONTRIBUTIONS.
THE PILOTS ASSOCIATION SAYS IT
WAS IMPROVED 69 PERCENT OF THE
UNITED AND CONTINENTAL WHO
VOTED.
THEY HAVE A MAJOR CONCESSION
EXPANDING THE USE OF LARGER JETS
FOR REGIONAL FLIGHTS.
THEY OLD 70 SEATS OR MORE.
THOUSANDS OF BAY AREA UNION
NURSES HOLD A ONE-DAY STRIKE ON
CHRISTMAS EVE STARTING THE
MORNING OF DECEMBER 24TH.
THE CALIFORNIA NURSE'S
ASSOCIATION SAYS THE STRIKE
EFFECTS 7 BAY AREA HOSPITALS
OPERATED BETTER HEALTH AND TWO
MORE SAN JOSE HOSPITALS
AFFILIATED WITH THE HOSPITAL
CORPORATION OF AMERICA.
THIS WOULD BE THE 8TH STRIKE BUY
CNA SINCE SEPTEMBER LAST YEAR.
IT HAS JUNIOR LEADERS AND
HOSPITAL MANAGERS REMAIN AT ODDS
OVER STAFFING LEVELS HEALTH
BENEFITS AND OTHER CONTRACT
ISSUES.
>>> OAKLAND WANTS TO BUILD A NEW
JOB CENTER BUT SAYS THE PLAN TO
PAY FOR IT IS A SELL OUT FOR THE
COMMUNITY.
THAT IS BECAUSE THE MONEY WOULD
COME FROM REVENUES GENERATED BY
A NEW BILLBOARD NEAR THE BAY
BRIDGE TOLL PLAZA.
THE STORY FROM ABC 7 NEWS
REPORTER.
>> ONE PLIGHT IS ANOTHER CRUCIAL
FUNDING SOURCE.
THAT'S THE GIST OF THE
CONTROVERSY OVER HOW TO PAY FOR
A NEW JOB ATTICA REAR RESOURCE
CENTER.
IT WOULD FUND THE CENTER WITH
PROCEED FROM FIVE NEW BRIGHT AND
SHINY BILLBOARDS ALONG THE
FREEWAY AT THE BAY BRIDGE
LANDING.
THEY WOULD JOIN THE THREE THAT
ARE ALREADY THERE.
>> IT IS A MONDAY STROSS CITY I
WILL GRANT YOU THAT BUT THOSE
DECISIONS HAVE BEEN MADE IN
NEGOTIATIONS.
SOME OF THE REVENUE FROM THE
BILLBOARD OUGHT TO FUND THE JOB
CENTER.
>> TO SHOW SUPPORT THEY HAVE A
NUMBER OF COMMUNITY MEMBERS TO
HOLD A PRAYER SERVICE.
IT WOULD HOUSE THE CAREER CENTER
ON THE SECOND FLOOR.
THE PROPOSED FIELDS FROM
BILLBOARD PLACEMENT FROM THE
CASH IS ULTIMATELY A BAD ONE FOR
THE COMMUNITY.
>> WE ALL WANT JOBS AND A JOBS
CENTER.
TO BASE IT ON POLLUTING OUR
LANDSCAPE TEST TRYING TO PIT US
AGAINST EACH OTHER.
THAT IS THE INTENTION OF THIS.
>> THEY HAVE ONE JOB TRAINING
CENTER THEY HELPED THOUSANDS OF
THE MOST TROUBLED TO GET GOOD
SKILLS.
THE ENDS DO JUSTIFY THE MEANS
WHEN IT COLES TO CRIME AND
UNEMPLOYMENT.
>>> THINGS ARE TIGHT RIGHT NOW.
THEY HELP THE PROGRAM IT WOULD
GENERATE FUNDS IF THE FUNDS ARE
ALLOCATED TO THE RIGHT PLACE IT
WOULD BE A PLUS PLUS.
>>> TAXI DRIVERS SAY APPS CAN
STEEL THEIR BUSINESS SO THEY ARE
GETTING EVEN WITH AN APP OF
THEIR OWN.
HOW IT COULD HELP YOU GET AROUND
TOWN?
THAT'S COMING UP.
>>> HERE IS A LIVE LOOK FROM THE
CAM SHOWING YOU A SLICE OF THE
BAY.
WE ARE ALL EXPERIENCING COLD
WEATHER.
IT IS NOT EVEN OFFICIALLY WINTER
YET.
>> WE WILL HAVE
>> AN GRACE I HAVE CAMPAIGN OF
THEIR OWN WITH AN APP THAT HCALS
A TAXI TO PICK YOU UP.
WHILE THE OTHER APPS ARE BUTTING
HEADS WITH GOVERNMENT REGULATOR
THIS IS ONE IS WORKING WITH
THEM.
>> AS HE DRIVES HIS TAXI THROUGH
THE BUMPY STREETS IN SAN
FRANCISCO THEY START TO RING.
THE PHONE IS STARTING A BRAND
NEW APP CALLED FLYWHEEL.
IT LOOKS LIKE THIS A MAP OF THE
PARTICIPATING CABS IN THE CITY.
>> YOU PUSH ONE BUTTON.
THE ONE NEAREST GETS ASSIGNED TO
YOU.
>> SOME WERE USING IT BEFORE THE
TOWN CARS.
IT IS BEING REBORN AS FLYWHEEL
COMPLETE WITH BOLD NEW
ADVERTISING ANNA PROMISE TO HELP
CABBIES COMPLETE WITH THE BLACK
CARS AND DRIVERS WITH THE PINK
MUSTACHES.
>> THEY GET 20-30 PERCENT MORE
RIDES A DAY BY HAVING THESE
MOBILE APPSABLE TO ACCESS THEIR
VEHICLES REAL TIME.
>> IT IS IN A THIRD OF SAN
FRANCISCO TAXIS TO THE OTHER
COMMUNICATION DEVICE.
>> NOW WE HAVE THE POWER OF A
CELL PHONE.
>> FOR CAB COMPANIES IT COULD
REPLACE DISPATCH SYSTEMS OR WORK
ALONG SIDE THE TWO-WAY RADIO TO
GIVE THE BIRD'S-EYE VIEW OF
WHERE THE DRIVERS ARE.
>> I NEED FOUR IN ABOUT 10-12
MINUTES.
ANYBODY INTERESTED?
>> BY WORKING WITH DISPATCHERS
INSTEAD OF GOING AROUND THEM
THEY HAVE MANAGED TO GET BROAD
SUPPORT FROM CAB COMPANIES.
>> THREE ASSIGNED I NEED ONE
MORE.
>> WHILE THEY BATTLE FROM STATE
REGULATORS FLYWHEEL ARE THE
GROWING ENDORSEMENT FROM THE
CITY.
>> THEY PLAN TO GET ALL
COMPANIES USING TRANSITIONS.
IN SAN FRANCISCO JONATHAN BLOOM
ABC 7 NEWS.
>>> GIVING BACK AND SHARING THE
WEALTH FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
THE BUILDING HOUSING THE
NONPROFIT GLIDE WAS PACKED WITH
PEOPLE.
EVERYONE RECEIVED A BLANKET.
THIS IS THE 16TH YEAR IN A ROW
THEY HAD MAIN KETS A -- BLANKET
AND PASSED THEM OUT TO THOSE IN
NEED.
THEY HOLD THE PROMISE OF HELPING
PARALYZE PEOPLE WALK.
THESE EXPERIMENTAL DEVICES COST
10'S OF THOUSANDS OF DOLLARS.
NOW A SMALLER CHEAPER COMMERCIAL
VERSION IS HELPING PATIENTS
REGAIN THEIR MOBILITY.
ABC 7 NEWS HAS A LOOK.
>> SHE WAS -- HE WAS A MARATHON
RUNNER BEFORE HE WAS LEFT
PARTIALLY PARALYZED.
>> I WOULDN'T REGAIN MUCH
MOBILITY AT ALL.
>> HE WAS A GEOLOGIST BEFORE A
MASSIVE STROKE DEVASTATED HIS
SPEECH AND MUCH OF THE RIGHT
SIDE OF HIS BODY.
>> WHEN HE FIRST HAD HIS STROKE
HE COULDN'T MOVE OR TALK.
>> NOW BOTH MEN ARE GAINING BACK
MOBILITY WITH KICK START A
SCALED DOWN VERSION OF AN EX OWE
SKELET
SKELETON.
IT HELPS THEM MOVE THEIR LIMBS.
>> IT HELPS WITH PEOPLE WITH
SPINAL CORD INJURIES IT IS
BILATERAL.
THEY ARE ALSO QUITE EXPENSIVE.
>> FORMER DIRECTOR OF PHYSICAL
THERAPY.
HE LIKES THAT KICK START HAS
LIMITED MOVEMENT PRO FEPEL THEI
LEGS WITH A WALKING MOTION
WITHOUT THE USE OF THE MOTOR.
>> IF YOU DON'T DO IT YOURSELF,
IF YOU DON'T INITIATE HIP
FLEXORS OR DUE TRY TO FLEX YOUR
KNEE OR HEEL THE DEVICE CAN'T DO
ERG FOR YOU.
>> AS ERIC PUSHES FORWARD WITH
HIS LEFT LEG THE BRACE ON THE
RIGHT RELICE IT IS AS HE LIFTS
HIS RIGHT FOOT FORWARD.
HIS WIFE SAYS THE ADDED PUSH
ALLOWED ERIC TO CLIMB THE STEEP
HILLS IN THE SAN FRANCISCO
NEIGHBORHOOD REBUILDING HIS
COORDINATION AND MUSCLE
STRENGTH.
>> HE IS NOT HIKING UP HIS HIP
AND WALKING WITH HIS KNEE OUT
AND LEG STIFF.
THOSE ARE MAJOR THINGS.
>> THE REHABILITATION IS MORE
CHALLENGING AFTER HIS INJURY.
HE WAS ONLY ABLE TO USE HIS LEG
MUSCLES IN A SWIMMING POOL BUT
OVER THE LAST SEVERAL MONTHS
WITH KICK START BRACES ON BOTH
LEGS HE IS TAKING HIS FIRST
LIMITED STEPS WITH THE HELP OF A
WALKER.
>> WORKING SLOWLY MY BODY IS
BECOMING USED TO IT.
NOW WE ARE SEEING VERY STRONG
GAINS I WOULD SAY.
>> QUICK START IS DESIGNED FOR
PATIENTS TO USE AT HOME IT HAS
TO BE PRESCRIBED A PHYSICIAN AND
FITED BY A TRAINED SPECIALIST.
SINCE THE COMPANY IS LESS THAN A
YEAR OLD KICK START HAS
PROVIDERS IN FOUR CITIES
INCLUDING SAN FRANCISCO.
THE PRICE $7,800.
INSURANCE COVERAGE VARIES.
BUT FOR PATIENTS LIKE ERIC AND
VAUGHN THIS HAS HELPED THEM TAKE
CRITICAL STEPS ON THEIR ROAD TO
RECOVERY.
>> I HAVE EVERY REASON TO BELIEF
I AM MAKING PROGRESS AND MOVING
TOWARDS IT.
>> CAROLYN SAYS DESIGNERS
BELIEVE KICK START COULD HELP
PATIENTS WEAKENED BY MUSCULAR
DYSTROPHY AND ALS.
THEY ARE RELEASING DATA FROM A
CLINICAL TRIAL EARLY NEXT YEAR.
WE MIGHT GET A BREAK FROM THE
RAIN TODAY MAYBE.
HERE IS LOUISE SAW.
-- HERE IS LISA.
>> IF YOU ARE IN THE SOUTH BAY
IT IS LOOKING MORE LIKELY.
LIVE LOOK OUTSIDE FROM THE ROOF
CAMERA.
CLOUDS KEEPING US NICE AND MILD
THIS MORNING.
I WILL LET YOU KNOW HOW LONG
THIS BREAK WILL LAST.
FULL ACCU-WEATHER FORECAST IS
NEXT.
>>> THANK YOU LISA.
ALSO WE ARE GOING TO CHECK OUT A
TOY THAT COULD CHANGE A YOUNG
GIRL'S L
>> JONATHAN BLOOM EXPLAINS IT IS
QUITE DIFFERENT THAN ANY DOLL
HOUSE YOU HAVE EVER SEEN.
>> IN CASE YOU ARE WONDERING
THAT'S AN ELECTRIC FIREPLACE IN
AN IMAGINARY SKI CABIN.
>> IT APPEARS YOU CAN PUT STAIRS
TO GO UP.
>> IT WAS BUILT WITH A SOURCE
SPEEGSLY FOR GIRLS AGES 6-10.
>> THERE AREN'T MANY TOYS FOR
GIRLS IT IS JUST DOLLS AND
PRINCESSES.
>> THEY STARTED THEIR TOY
COMPANY AT STANFORD STARTUP
BUSINESS ACCELERATOR AFTER
GRADUATING IN A CLASS OF MOSTLY
MALE ENGINEERS.
>> NEEDS TO BE DONE AT AN
EARLIER STAGE TO GET GIRLS TO
UNDERSTAND SCIENCE AND
ENGINEERING ARE FUN.
>> WHILE MOST TEACH INTERIOR
DESIGN IT TEACHES STRUCTURAL
ENGINEERING.
>> THESE ARE THE BUILDING PIECES
FOR THE FURNITURE.
INCLUDED IN THAT IS A LITTLE
MINI CATALOG OF IDEAS THAT YOU
CAN MAKE.
>> THERE IS AN ELECTRIC MOTOR
FOR FANS ELEVATORS AND WASHING
MACHINES.
THEY SHOT THIS VIDEO OF KIDS
TRYING IT OUT.
THE ORDERS ARE POURING IN.
>> IT HAS BEEN BEYOND ANYTHING
WE EXPECTED.
>> ALICE AND PATINA ALREADY SOLD
2,000 TOY THIS IS HOLIDAY
SEASON.
THE LATEST BATCH OF 1,000 IS
WELL ON ITS WAY TO SELLING OUT.
BETWEEN NOW AND CHRISTMAS THEY
WILL BE SELLING LONG HOURS.
>> WORKING TOGETHER THEY CAN
LABEL BOX AND SHIP ABOUT ONE
ORDER A MINUTE.
>> IT IS NOT GLAMOROUS.
THAT'S WHAT I LEARNED ABOUT
UNFINISHED IN THE LAST YEAR.
IT'S BY DOING EVERYTHING THAT
HAS TO HAPPEN.
>> BUT SEEING KIDS CAPTIVATED
MAKES IT ALL WORTH IT.
>> THE PARENTS ARE LIKE I AM NOT
DONE.
>> JONATHAN BLOOM ABC 7 NEWS.
>>> WELL METEOROLOGIST LISA
ARGEN IS HERE NOW.
IF YOU ARE HOPING FOR SUNNY
LOVELY WARM WEATHER, FORGET
ABOUT IT.
>> YEAH, SERIOUSLY.
>> WE ARE A LITTLE WARMER,
THOUGH, WITH ALL OF THE CLOUDS
AROUND WE ARE IN THE 40s.
UPPER 40s DOWNTOWN.
STILL PLENTY OF LOW LEVEL
MOISTURE AROUND THE BAY AREA.
RIGHT NOW WE ARE TAKING YOU TO
TAHOE HEAVENLY MOUNTAIN RESORT.
YOU ARE LOOKING AT CLOUDY SKIES
AND TEMPERATURES IN THE LOW 30s
RIGHT NOW AT THE TAHOE VALLEY
AIRPORT.
SOUTHWEST WIND AT 14 GUSTING TO
20 MILES PER HOUR.
WINDY CONDITIONS IN THE AREA
WITH A HIGH OF 37 TODAY WITH
SNOW AND BACK HOME, ISN'T THIS A
COOL SHOT FROM OUR EAST BAY.
YOU CAN SEE ALL OF THE CLOUDS
AND THAT OFFICIAL SUNRISE AFTER
7.
SOME OF YOU MAY SEE A FEW PEEKS
OF SUN.
OTHERWISE LOW LEVEL MOISTURE
AROUND RAINY MIST, DRIZZLE AND
LIGHT RAIN RIGHT NOW.
IT IS FALL YOU WILL GO UNDER THE
RADAR BEAM.
THERE IS A LITTLE MIST AND
DRIZZLE OUT THERE FROM THE NORTH
BEYDOUN TO SAN FRANCISCO.
IF YOU ARE HEADED OUT THIS
MORNING DO BE CAREFUL.
YOU WILL NOTICE THE TEMPERATURES
ARE PRETTY MILD WITH 49 SAN
FRANCISCO, 47 IN OAKLAND.
EVEN IN OUR NORTH AND EASTERN
VALLEY LOWER TO MID 40s.
THAT PUTS US MUCH, MUCH WARMER
THAN YESTERDAY.
ANYWHERE FROM 5 -- 3 TO 5
DEGREES TO 11-12 DEGREES WARMER.
STARTING OUT THE MILDER
CONDITIONS BUT THERE'S A PRICE
TO PAY FOR THAT.
THE LOW LEVEL MOISTURE WITH THE
MOISTURE AND THE LIGHT RAIN
THROUGH OUT THE MORNING HOURS
AND THE AFTERNOON.
IT WILL BE KIND OF DAMP AGAIN.
RAINFALL AMOUNTS NOT AMOUNTING
TO TOO MUCH AS WE ARE IN BETWEEN
SYSTEMS.
OUR VISIBILITY ANYWHERE FROM 3
MILES HALF-MOON BAY TO BETTER
THAN THAT AROUND MOUNTAIN VIEW
AND SAN JOSE.
SHOWERS THIS MORNING AND THIS
AFTERNOON.
THE NEXT SIGNIFICANT SYSTEM
HEADS OUR WAY OVERNIGHT TONIGHT.
THAT WILL BRING IN A RAINY
MONDAY MORNING COMMUTE.
HERE IS OUR SATELLITE AND RADAR
COMPOSITE.
THERE IS THE WARM FRONTAL SECTOR
OF THE NEXT SYSTEM AND THAT IS
ALLOWING FOR THE CLOUDS, LIGHT
SHOWERS.
WITHIN THE NEXT 12-18 HOURS THIS
IS WHAT WE GET INTO.
THIS MORNING WE ARE LOOKING WET
FROM SANTA ROSA TO SAN FRANCISCO
AS YOU GO THROUGH THE AFTERNOON
PRETTY MOIST.
DON'T LOOK FOR SUNSHINE UNLESS
YOU ARE AROUND THE SANTA CRUZ
AREA.
FROM SONOMA TO NAPA PUSHING
THROUGH 5, 6, 7:00 TOMORROW
MORNING THE FRONT CLEARS BY
MIDDAY TOMORROW.
RAINFALL AMOUNTS WITH THIS NEXT
SYSTEM LIGHT IN THE NORTH BAY
ANYWHERE FROM HALF AN INCH TO AN
INCH.
AROUND SAN FRANCISCO EAST BAY
MAY BE A QUARTER OF AN INCH UP
TO A TENTH OF AN INCH IN THE
SOUTH BAY.
UPPER 40s TO LOW 50s TODAY.
CHILLY BUT MILDER THAN
YESTERDAY.
SUNNY BREAKS HERE AND THERE FROM
THE SOUTH BAY THE CENTRAL COAST
TO THE LIGHT SHOWERS HEAVIER
RAIN TONIGHT A BREAK COMES IN
TUESDAY AND WEDNESDAY.
MORE RAIN THURSDAY, FRIDAY,
SATURDAY.
LOOKS LIKE IT WANTS TO KEEP
ONGOING.
>> MOIST.
ISN'T THAT AN UNDER @Ñ
>> LIGHT SHOWERS ARNSD.
MILD TEMPERATURES.
WARMER THAN YESTERDAY BUT STILL
SHOWERS AROUND.
53 OAKLAND SAN JOSE.
THE NEXT WET WEATHER SYSTEM OR
ORGANIZED RAIN COMES IN
OVERNIGHT TONIGHT THROUGH THE
MONDAY MORNING COMMUTE.
THEN WE CLEAR ON OUT MAYBE HALF
INCH TO AN INCH OF RAIN.
BREAK MIDWEEK.
HEAVIER RAIN NEXT WEEK INTO NEXT
WEEKEND.
LOOKS LIKE CHRISTMAS COULD BE
WET, TOO.
>> THAT IS GOING TO DO IT FOR
US.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US ON THE
ABC 7 SUNDAY MORNING NEWS.
I AM CAROLYN TOWERS ALONG WITH
LISA ARGEN.
ABC 7 NEWS CONTINUES AT 9:00
THIS MORNING.
ABC 7'S GIFT TO YOU THIS HOLIDAY
SEASON IS A OPTIONS FOR SMART
PHONES AND TABLETS.
DOWNLOAD OUR APP FOR YOUR iPHONE
ANDROID AND TABLET AND THE
KINDLE FIRE.
ABC 7 NEWS APP IS AVAILABLE FOR
ALL THOSE DEVICES AS WELL AS
>>> THIS MORNING, A SPECIAL
EDITION OF "GOOD MNG
EDITION OF "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA" AS THE PRESIDENT
PREPARES TO VISIT A SHATTERED
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WHERE WE
ARE LEARNING MUCH MORE ABOUT THE
YOUNG MAN BEHIND THE WORST
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
AMERICAN HISTORY.
>> HE ALWAYS CARRIED A
BRIEFCASE, AND THAT'S WHAT
STICKS OUT MOST IN MY MIND.
>> DID HIS MOTHER, THE FIRST
VICTIM, GIVE HIM TARGET
PRACTICE?
>>> ALSO THIS MORNING, FOR THE
FIRST TIME WE ARE HEARING A
SURVIVAL STORY FROM INSIDE HIS
SCHOOL.