MIND.
>> WE REMEMBER THE VICTIMS AND
BEGIN A NEW NATIONAL
CONVERSATION THIS MORNING.
>>> AND GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE.
I'M ROB NELSON.
>> I'M SUNNY HOSTIN, PAULA FARIS
IS ON ASSIGNMENT.
WE BEGIN WITH THE LATEST.
FROM THE TRAGEDY IN SANDY HOOK.
THERE WILL BE FRESH GRIEF AS THE
FIRST FUNERALS ARE HELD FOR THE
VICTIMS.
TWO LITTLE BOYS, JACK PINTO AND
NOAH POZNER WILL BE REMEMBERED.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA SPOKE OF
THEIR LOSS AND THE OTHERS AT A
VIGIL LAST NIGHT.
SAYING WE, AS A NATION, CANNOT
TOLERATE THIS KIND OF VIOLENCE
ANYMORE.
WE'RE LEARNING NEW DETAILS ABOUT
THE SHOOTER HIMSELF, ADAM LANZA,
AND HOW HE MANAGED TO CARRY OUT
HIS DEADLY MASSACRE.
WE BEGIN WITH COVERAGE FROM
ABC'S TAHMAN BRADLEY.
>> HE JOINS US LIVE FROM NEWTOWN
WHERE THE GRIEVING WILL TAKE A
MORE PRIVATE TURN LATER TODAY.
GOOD MORNING, TAHMAN.
>> Reporter: SUNNY AND ROB, GOOD
MORNING TO YOU.
TODAY IS GOING TO BE ANOTHER
TOUGH DAY FOR THIS HEARTBROKEN
COMMUNITY.
FUNERALS WILL BEGIN TODAY AND
TOMORROW.
FOR SOME OF THE VICTIMS.
AND LAST NIGHT'S PRAYER VIGIL,
VISITED BY PRESIDENT OBAMA, IS
SOMETHING THAT THIS COMMUNITY
AND THE COUNTRY WILL NOT SOON
FORGET.
>> OLIVIA.
JOSEPHINE.
>> Reporter: THE MORE THAN 900
MOURNERS WHO PACKED NEWTOWN HIGH
SCHOOL HEARD AN EMOTIONAL
PRESIDENT OBAMA ADMIT THE
COUNTRY HAS FAILED THEM.
>> SINCE I HAVE BEEN PRESIDENT
THIS IS THE FOURTH TIME WE HAVE
COME TOGETHER TO COMFORT A
GRIEVING COMMUNITY TORN APART BY
MASS SHOOTINGS.
>> Reporter: HE SAID HE'LL USE
THE POWER OF THE PRESIDENCY TO
STOP TRAGEDIES LIKE THE MASSACRE
OF 26 CHILDREN AND ADULTS AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
TO END THEM, WE MUST CHANGE.
>> Reporter: OUTSIDE THE VIGIL
WHERE PRESIDENT OBAMA SPOKE, AN
EMOTIONAL REACTION FROM A
SHATTERED COMMUNITY TO THE
PRESIDENT'S VISIT.
>> IT WAS VERY TOUCHING AND
TO -- IT DID MEAN A LOT.
>> WE HAVE TO PROTECT THE KIDS.
LIKE HE SAID, THAT'S HOW WE'LL
BE JUDGED.
>> Reporter: NEW AND CHILLING
DETAILS ABOUT GUNMAN ADAM
LANZA'S PATH THROUGH IS THE
SCHOOL HAVE EMERGED.
ACCORDING TO THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT, THE RAMPAGE ENDED
TEN MINUTES AFTER IT BEGAN WHEN
THE GUNMAN HEARD WAILING SIRENS
APPROACHING WHILE HE WAS IN THE
SECOND CLASSROOM, AND SHE SHOT
HIMSELF ONCE IN THE HEAD.
>> WE SURMISE IT WAS DURING THE
SECOND CLASSROOM EPISODE HE
HEARD RESPONDERS COMING AND
APPARENTLY, THAT, HAD DECIDED TO
TAKE HIS OWN LIFE.
>> Reporter: NEW CLUES ABOUT THE
20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER.
COMPUTERS AND VIDEOS WERE
REMOVED FROM THE LANZA FAMILY
HOME THIS WEEKEND THAT COULD
PROVIDE CLUES INTO HIS MOTIVE.
FRIENDS OF ADAM'S MURDERED
MOTHER, NANCY, SAY SHE WAS
INCREASINGLY CONCERNED ABOUT HER
SON'S BEHAVIORAL ISSUES OVER THE
LAST FEW MONTHS.
>> I THINK IT WAS JUST GETTING
DIFFICULT FOR HER TO TRY TO GET
HIM INTO REGULAR LIFE.
>> Reporter: ALL OF THE SCHOOLS
IN THE AREA ARE CLOSED TODAY.
STUDENTS FROM SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WILL RESUME
CLASSES AT A NEIGHBORING SCHOOL
IN A MATTER OF DAYS.
ROB AND SUNNY?
>> IN A TRAGEDY LIKE THIS, IT'S
SO IMPORTANT TO TRY TO REMEMBER
THE VICTIMS, PERHAPS, MORE THAN
THE GUNMAN HERE.
BUT WE HAVE LEARNED SOME MORE
ABOUT ADAM LANZA, CORRECT?
>> Reporter: THAT'S EXACTLY
RIGHT.
ABC NEWS HAS LEARNED THAT ADAM
LANZA AND HIS MOTHER VISITED AN
AREA GUN RANGE.
INVESTIGATORS ARE TRYING TO
DETERMINE WHETHER OR NOT HE SHOT
THERE, LEARNED HOW TO SHOOT AT
THE GUN RANGE.
NOW, INVESTIGATORS HAVE BEEN
CANVASSING LOCAL GUN RANGES AND
LOCAL GUN DEALERS TO FIND OUT IF
LANZA TRIED TO PURCHASE GUNS
THERE AND WHETHER OR NOT HE WAS
A SHOOTER.
HE CARRIED MULTIPLE 30-ROUND
MAGAZINES AND TWO HANDGUNS INTO
THE SCHOOL AND A RIFLE WAS FOUND
IN HIS CAR IN THE PARKING LOT.
ROB AND SUNNY?
>> ABC'S TAHMAN BRADLEY
REPORTING FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, THANK YOU.
>>> AS THE NATION STRUGGLES TO
COME TO GRIPS WITH THIS
HORRIFIC TRAGEDY, WE'RE LEARNING
MORE ABOUT THOSE WHO LOST THEIR
LIVES.
>> DAVID MUIR HAS SOME OF THE
PERSONAL SNAPSHOTS JUST
EMERGING.
>> Reporter: A SONG FROM ONE OF
THE LITTLE GIRLS WHO DID NOT
SURVIVE.
ANA WAS JUST 6.
HER FATHER, A JAZZ MUSICIAN.
SITTING HERE BESIDE HER BROTHER.
>> ONE, TWO, THREE, READY AND
GO.
♪ COME NOW ALMIGHTY KING
♪ HELP US GUIDE AND TO SEE
>> Reporter: HER BROTHER WAS
ALSO IN THAT SCHOOL.
HE SURVIVED.
HERE, PRACTICING A SONG WITH HER
PARENTS.
♪ AMEN
>> Reporter: IN THE END,
FLASHING HER SMILE.
WE'RE ALSO LEARNING MORE ABOUT
EMILIE PARKER.
WHO WAS 6.
SHE WOULD OFTEN CARRY WITH HER
MARKERS AND CRAYONS TO DRAW
PICTURES FOR PEOPLE SHE THOUGHT
WERE SAD.
THIS COMMUNITY, SO MOVED BY HER
FATHER, WHO BRAVELY DESCRIBED
HIS LITTLE GIRL AND HIS LOSS.
>> SHE WAS THE TYPE OF PERSON
THAT COULD LIGHT UP A ROOM.
SHE, UM -- SHE ALWAYS HAD
SOMETHING KIND TO SAY ABOUT
ANYBODY.
>> Reporter: HE SPOKE OF THE
PARENTS OF THE OTHER 19
CHILDREN, OLIVIA WAS JUST
LEARNING THE ROSARY AND WOULD
LEAD HER FAMILY IN GRACE EVERY
NIGHT BEFORE DINNER.
JESSE WAS LEARNING TO RIDE
HORSEBACK AND WAS LOOKING
FORWARD TO HIS FATHER COMING TO
SCHOOL ON FRIDAY TO WATCH HIM
MAKE A GINGERBREAD HOUSE.
CATHERINE AND HER BEAUTIFUL RED
HAIR.
GRACE McDONNELL, WHOSE
GRANDMOTHER SAID GRACE LOVED
PLAYING DRESSUP, LOVED WEARING
GRANDMA'S JEWELRY.
AND THE PRINCIPAL, DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG IS BELIEVED TO HAVE
TURN ON THE THE P.A. IN THE
CHAOS, TO WARN THE OTHER
TEACHERS.
NOW IT'S BELIEVED SHE HEADED
STRAIGHT TOWARD THE GUNMAN,
TOWARD THE SOUND OF GUNFIRE TO
SAVE THE STUDENTS.
MARY SHERLOCK, THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST, RIGHT THERE WITH
HER.
THE TEACHER'S AIDES, RACHEL AND
ANNE MARIE.
AND TEACHER LAUREN ROUSSEAU,
WHOSE FATHER SAID SHE DIED WITH
HER LITTLE KIDS.
AND VICTORIA SOTO, WHOSE FAMILY
SAID IT WAS CLEAR WHEN SHE WAS
FOUND THAT SHE WAS TRYING TO
SHIELD HER FIRST GRADE STUDENTS.
>> AND THERE'S KIDS NOW THAT
WILL BE ABLE TO SAY THAT THEY'RE
HERE TODAY BECAUSE SHE
SACRIFICED HER LIFE SO THEY
COULD LIVE ANOTHER DAY.
>> Reporter: DAVID MUIR, ABC
NEWS, NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> WHAT A MOMENT FOR THAT FATHER
TO STAND UP TO THE MIKES AND
ADDRESS THE WORLD LIKE THAT.
INCREDIBLY NOWERFUL, THE
STRENGTH HE HAD TO DO THAT.
>>> SCHOOLS AROUND THE COUNTRY
ARE REVIEWING SCHOOL SECURITY.
ADMINISTRATORS HAVE PLEDGED TO
HAVE EXTRA POLICE AND GUIDANCE
COUNSELORS ON HAND AS STUDENTS
RETURN TO THE CLASSROOM FOR THE
FIRST TIME SINCE THE SHOOTING.
>> TWO SCHOOL DISTRICTS IN
PITTSBURGH HAVE BEEN GIVEN
SPECIAL PERMISSION TO ARM THEIR
SECURITY GUARDS IN LIGHT OF THE
SHOOTING.
>>> AND WITH GUNS NOW AT THE
CENTER OF SO MUCH DEBATE, SOME
FACTS HERE.
ON BLACK FRIDAY, THE FBI DID
BACKGROUND CHECKS ON MORE THAN
154,000 PURCHASES OF FIREARMS.
IN NOVEMBER ALONE, AMERICANS
TRIED TO BUY 2 MILLION GUNS.
THE U.S. HAS MORE GUN DEALERS
AND STORES THAN SUPERMARKETS,
EVEN McDONALD'S.
HARD TO IMAGINE THAT.
MORE THAN 200 MILLION GUNS IN
ALL ON THE STREETS OF AMERICA.
>>> ONE GROUP THAT HAS BEEN
SILENT SINCE THE CONNECTICUT
SHOOTINGS HAS BEEN THE GUN LOBBY
ITSELF, THE NATIONAL RIFLE
ASSOCIATION.
THE USUALLY SOCIAL MEDIA-SAVVY
NRA HASN'T TWEETED OR POSTED
ANYTHING ON ITS FACEBOOK PAGE
SINCE FRIDAY.
THE FACEBOOK PAGE WAS TAKEN DOWN
A DAY AFTER IT BOASTED OF
REACHING 1.7 MILLION LIKES.
>> DEAFENING SILENCE PERHAPS.
>>> COMING UP, WHAT TO TELL YOUR
CHILDREN AS THEY GO BACK TO
SCHOOL TODAY.
>>> AND THE MORNING'S OTHER NEWS
TODAY.
SIGNS OF PROGRESS AS WE GET
CLOSER AND CLOSER TO WHAT SEEMS
LIKE BIG NEWS LAST WEEK, THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
>>> AND KATE MIDDLETON STEPS OUT
FOR THE FIRST TIME SINCE BEING
HOSPITALIZED.
STAY WITH US.
STAY WIT
♪
>>> IN BROOKFIELD, WISCONSIN,
THE SIKH TEMPLE, STILL REELING
FROM ITS OWN MASS SHOOTING HELD
A PRAYER VIGIL FOR VICTIMS IN
NEWTOWN LAST NIGHT.
SIX PEOPLE WERE KILLED THERE
WHEN A GUNMAN BURST INTO THAT
TEMPLE AND OPENED FIRE LAST
AUGUST.
>>> UNFORTUNATELY MORE GUN
VIOLENCE NEWS TO BRING YOU THIS
MORNING.
THE TOPEKA, KANSAS, POLICE FORCE
IS IN MOURNING THIS MORNING
AFTER TWO OF ITS OFFICERS WERE
GUNNED DOWN.
>> BOTH MEN WERE SHOT IN THE
HEAD WHEN THEY RESPONDED TO A
REPORT OF A SUSPICIOUS VEHICLE
OUTSIDE A GROCERY STORE.
AND NOW THERE'S AN INTENSE
MANHUNT FOR THE SUSPECT,
BELIEVED TO BE A 22-YEAR-OLD
MAN.
>>> IN SUBURBAN CHICAGO, POLICE
SURROUNDED A HOME DEPOT AS THEY
SEARCHED FOR TWO MEN WHO ROBBED
ANOTHER STORE EARLIER.
THEY SAY THE ARMED ROBBERS WORE
SKI MASKS WHEN THEY ENTERED A
NEARBY RADIO SHACK AND TOOK
EQUIPMENT AND CASH.
A POLICE DOG THEN FOLLOWED THEIR
TRAIL TO THE HOME DEPOT.
>>> ALSO, SHOPPERS AT A SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA MALL RAN FOR COVER
AFTER A GUNMAN OPENED FIRE THERE
OVER THE WEEKEND.
POLICE SAY THE SHOOTER GOT OFF
50 SHOTS INTO THE AIR AND ON THE
GROUND BEFORE LAYING HIS GUN
DOWN AND SIMPLY GIVING UP.
INVESTIGATORS SAY HE WAS
APPARENTLY UNHAPPY ABOUT HIS
LIFE AND THE SHOOTING WAS A WAY
OF LETTING OFF SOME STEAM.
THANKFULLY, NO ONE WAS SERIOUSLY
HURT.
>>> THERE ARE REPORTS OF
PROGRESS IN THE FISCAL CLIFF
TALKS.
SOURCES SAY HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER IS NOW WILLING TO
CONSIDER A TAX INCREASE FOR
THOSE MAKING MORE THAN $1
MILLION A YEAR.
IN RETURN FOR SPENDING CUTS AND
REFORMS.
BOTH SIDES ARE EXPRESSING
OPTIMISM A DEAL CAN BE MADE
BEFORE TAX RATES GO UP AND
AUTOMATIC SPENDING CUTS KICK IN
TWO WEEKS FROM TODAY.
>>> KATE MIDDLETON IS CLEARLY
FEELING A LOT BETTER.
SHE MADE HER FIRST PUBLIC
APPEARANCE SINCE BEING RELEASED
FROM THE HOSPITAL FOR THE SEVERE
MORNING SICKNESS.
>> THE ROYAL MOTHER TO BE WAS A
PRESENTER LAST NIGHT AT THE BBC
SPORTS PERSONALITY OF THE YEAR
AWARDS.
AFTER MORE THAN A WEEK AT REST,
SHE LOOKED ENERGETIC, HEALTHY,
AND STRONG.
>>> WHEN WE COME BACK, OUR TOP
STORY.
THE TRAGEDY AT SANDY HOOK.
WE'LL HEAR REMARKABLE COMMENTS
ABOUT THE ONLY SURVIVOR FROM ONE
CLASSROOM.
>>> AND BACK TO SCHOOL.
WHAT TO TELL YOUR KIDS AS THEY
HEAD TO CLASS TODAY.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
HELLO?
[ Sea ] HI!
THIS IS THE SEA CALLING.
WHEN'S THE LAST TIME
YOU VISITED ME?
WHEN I WENT SURFING.
I LOVE TO SURF.
CAN YOU IMAGINE
SURFING IN THE MIDDLE OF ME?
IN THE MIDDLE OF YOU?
OH YES!
[ giggles ] NICE MOVES!
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
OUR BIGGEST DECEMBER
SALES EVENT EVER.
GOING ON NOW.
CALL 1-800-ROYAL-CARIBBEAN.
[ Tylenol Bottle ]
ME TOO! AND NASAL CONGESTION.
[ Tissue Box ]
HE SAID NASAL CONGESTION.
YEAH...I HEARD HIM.
[ Female Announcer ] TYLENOL®
COLD MULTI-SYMPTOM NIGHTTIME
RELIEVES NASAL CONGESTION.
NYQUIL® COLD AND FLU DOESN'T.
>>> IT WILL BE ANOTHER VERY
SOMBER DAY IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AS FUNERAL SERVICES
BEGIN TODAY FOR TWO YOUNG
VICTIMS.
THAT FOLLOWS THE PRESIDENT'S
EMOTIONAL VISIT LAST NIGHT TO
THE TOWN.
HE MET PRIVATELY WITH FAMILY
MEMBERS WHO LOST LOVED ONES.
>> THE PRINCIPAL'S DAUGHTER SENT
A PICTURE OF THE PRESIDENT
CRADLING HER DAUGHTER.
SHE SENT A TWEET SAYING THAT MY
MOM WOULD BE SO PRUDE TO SEE THE
PRESIDENT HOLDING MY DAUGHTER,
BUT NOT AS PROUD AS I AM OF HER.
THE PRESIDENT THEN SPOKE.
>> THERE HAVE BEEN ALMOST DAILY
REPORTS OF VICTIMS, IN SMALL
TOWNS AND BIG CITIES ACROSS
AMERICA.
VICK CHIMS WHOSE MUCH OF TIME,
THEIR ONLY FAULT WAS BEING IN
THE WRONG PLACE AT THE WRONG
TIME.
WE CAN'T TOLERATE THIS ANYMORE.
>> AS THE PRESIDENT READ THE
FIRST NAME OF EACH YOUNG VICK
TESTIMONY OUT LOUD, THERE WERE
AUDIBLE SOBS AND CRIES.
>>> A FIRST GRADER FROM SANDY
HOOK IS THE SOLE SURVIVOR FROM
HER CLASS.
>> SHE HAD TO PLAY DEAD BEFORE
SHE COULD GET AWAY.
>> LARA SPENCER SPOKE WITH THE
PASTOR COUNSELING THE GIRL'S
FAMILY.
>> YOU HAVE A PARISHONER WHO WAS
THERE.
>> SHE RAN OUT OF THE BILLING
COVERED IN BLOOD FROM HEAD TO
TOE, AND THE FIRST WORDS TO HER
MOM WERE, MOMMY, I'M OKAY, BUT
ALL OF MY FRIENDS ARE DEAD.
>> WAS SHE THE ONLY CLILD IN
THAT CLASS WHO SURVIVED?
>> YES.
OF THOSE LEFT IN THE CLASSROOM,
SHE WAS THE LONE SURVIVOR.
>> WHAT DID SHE TELL HER MOM?
WHAT DID SHE SEE IN THERE?
>> SHE SAW SOMEONE SHE FELT WAS
ANGRY AND SOMEBODY SHE FELT WAS
VERY MAD.
>> HOW, AT 6 1/2 YEARS OLD, CAN
YOU BE THAT SMART, THAT BRAVE?
>> THINK IT'S IMPOSSIBLE OUTSIDE
OF DIVINE INTERVENTION.
SHE HAS WISDOM BEYOND HER YEARS.
>> HOW ARE THE MOM AND DAD
DOING?
>> THINK AS WELL AS YOU CAN
EXPECT THEM TO DO?
>> MAY MUST BE RELIEVED TO HAVE
THEIR CHARLD, BUT ON THE OTHER
HAND, SO MANY FEELINGS.
>> THE MOM TOLD ME THAT SHE WAS
SUFFERING FROM WHAT SHE CALLED
SURVIVOR'S GUILT.
BECAUSE SO MANY OF HER FRIENDS
NO LONGER HAVE THEIR CHILDREN.
BUT SHE HAS HERS.
>> ONE SURVIVOR OUT OF 16.
FOR PARENTS OF YOUNG CHILDREN,
THE QUESTION FOR DAYS.
HOW IN THIS SITUATION, WHAT DO
YOU TELL YOUR KIDS?
>> EARLIER THIS MORNING, I
TALKED TO DR. HAROLD KOPLEWICZ.
I ASKED WHAT AGE DO YOU START TO
TALK TO YOUR CHILDREN?
>> THINK IT DEPENDS ON THE
PARTICULAR CHILD.
THE RULE OF THUMB IS 5 YEARS OF
AGE.
ONE OF THE THINGS WE LIKE IS FOR
PARENTS TO BREAK THE NEWS TO THE
KIDS.
SAY SOMETHING TERRIBLE HAPPENED
IN A SCHOOL VERY FAR AWAY.
NOT SO FAR AWAY.
AND BECAUSE THIS TERRIBLE THING
HAPP
HAPPENED, WHERE KIDS WERE VERY
BADLY HURT, SCHOOL IS GOING TO
BE SAFER NOW.
THERE WILL BE MORE PRECAUTIONS
AT SCHOOL.
TAKE THE CUE FROM THE CHILD.
>> WHAT ABOUT THE CHILD THAT IS
AFRAID TO GO BACK TO SCHOOL ON
MONDAY MORNING?
>> THINK IT'S VERY IMPORTANT
THEY GO BACK TO SCHOOL.
THAT MEANS YOU HAVE TO REASSURE
THEM, YOU HAVE TO TELL THEM
ABOUT THE SAFETY OF THEIR --
YOUR SCHOOL, HOW RARE THESE
EVENTS ARE.
IF NECESSARY, YOU'RE GOING TO
CHANGE YOUR SCHEDULE AROUND AND
DRIVE YOUR CHILD TO SCHOOL OR
WALK YOUR CHILD TO SCHOOL,
BECAUSE IT'S REALLY IMPORTANT
THAT WE WANT TO MODEL RESILIENCE
AND WE WANT OUR CHILDREN TO BE
RESILIENT.
WE DON'T WANT TO DESTABILIZE
THEM BY THIS.
WE DON'T WANT THIS TERRIBLE
TOECHBT HAVE MORE NEGATIVE
EVENTS ON CHILDREN WHO WON'T GO
TO SCHOOL.
GETTING BACK TO SCHOOL AND INTO
THE ROUTINE IS ONE OF THE BEST
THINGS.
>> WHAT DID YOU TELL YOUR KIDS?
>> I HAVE A FIRST GRADER.
I DIDN'T TELL THE 6-YEAR-OLD
ANYTHING.
I SPOKE TO THE 10-YEAR-OLD.
I SAID THIS IS RARE, IT'S
HAPPENED.
IT'S A TERRIBLE TRAGEDY.
AND HE'S SAFE.
AND I'M ALWAYS HERE TO DISCUSS
WITH HIM WHATEVER ISSUES HE
WANTS TO TALK ABOUT.
>> SHOW THEM THE LOVE AND ASSURE
THEM OF SAFETY.
THAT HELPS.
>>> WELL, IN WASHINGTON, GUN
CONTROL ADVOCATES HELD A VIGIL
JOULT SIDE THE WHITE HOUSE LAST
NIGHT.
>> MANY OF THOSE TAKING PART
LOST FAMILIES TO GUN VIOLENCE.
THEY'RE PUSHING FOR TOUGHER GUN
LAWS AND DEMANDING ACTION.
>> NO QUESTION.
>>> UP NEXT, OUTSIDE REACTIONS
TO THE TRAGEDY.
>> HEART FELT MOMENTS AT NFL
GAMES AND ACROSS THE NATION.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[ Male Announcer ] When Ziggy
the cat appeared at their door,
he opened up
Jake's very private world.
At first, Jake's family
thought they saved Ziggy,
but his connection with Jake
has been a lifesaver.
For a love this strong,
his family only feeds him Iams.
Compared to other
leading brands,
it has 50% more
animal protein...
...to help keep Ziggy's body
as strong as a love
that reaches further
than anyone's words.
Iams. Keep Love Strong.
AND WITH MY BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CREDIT CARD,
I LOVE 'EM EVEN MORE.
I EARN 1% CASH BACK EVERYWHERE,
EVERY TIME.
2% ON GROCERIES.
3% ON GAS.
AUTOMATICALLY.
NO HOOPS TO JUMP THROUGH.
THAT'S 1% BACK ON...
[ toy robot sounds ]
2% ON PUMPKIN PIE.
AND APPLE.
3% BACK ON 4 TRIPS
TO THE AIRPORT.
IT'S AS EASY AS...
-[ man ] 1...
-[ woman ] 2...
[ woman ] 3.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CARD.
APPLY ONLINE OR AT
A BANK OF AMERICA NEAR YOU.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
HE IS A GOOD LITTLE MONKEY
AND ALWAYS VERY CURIOUS.
ONE DAY GEORGE GOT
AN IMPORTANT LETTER.
HE'S BUILT A ROCKET SHIP
TO TRAVEL INTO SPACE."
GOOGLE, HOW FAR IS EARTH
TO THE MOON?
THE MOON IS 238,900 MILES...
"THE GREAT MOMENT HAD COME."
3, 2, 1...
[ GIGGLING ]
♪
>>> WELCOME BACK.
WE ADJUST OUR USUAL "PULSE"
SEGMENT THIS MORNING FOR
SOME REACTIONS TO THE
CONNECTICUT MASSACRE.
THERE WERE MOMENTS OF SILENCE AT
EVERY NFL GAME YESTERDAY.
>> LAST NIGHT, BEFORE THE
49ers-PATS GAME, MASSACHUSETTS
SET OFF 26 FLARES, ONE FOR EACH
OF THE VICTIMS.
THE GIANTS WORE THE LETTERS
S.H.E.S. ON THEIR HELMETS,
REPRESENTING SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
VICTOR CRUZ REMEMBERED VICTIM
JACK PINTO.
>> IT WAS MOTION NAL.
I WAS FIGHTING BACK TEARS.
IT FELT GOOD TO HONOR A
FAMILY GOING THROUGH SO MUCH.
>> CRUZ CALLED THE FAMILY AFTER
HE LEARNS THAT HE WAS THEIR
BOY'S FAVORITE PLAYER.
THE PARENTS PLAN TO BURY LITTLE
JACK IN ONE OF CRUZ'S NUMBER 80
JERSEYS.
>>> ALSO OVER THE WEEKEND, A
UNIQUE AND STIRRING OPENING TO
"SATURDAY NIGHT LIVE."
♪ SILENT NIGHT HOLY NIGHT ALL IS
CALM ♪
>> THOSE WERE MEMBERS OF THE NEW
YORK CITY CHILDREN'S CHORUS,
SINGING THE CLASSIC, "SILENT
NIGHT."
THEY SUNG THE WHOLE SONG FOR THE
OPEN OF THE SHOW AND SAID THE
TRADITIONAL, LIVE FROM NEW YORK,
IT'S SATURDAY NIGHT.
>> THE COVER OF "THE CONNECTICUT
POST," THE HEADLINE, NOW, TEACH
THEM WELL.
TAKING ON THE PRESIDENT'S
MESSAGE SAYING, LOOK, THE LEGACY
OF SOCIETY IS HOW WE TAKE CARE
OF OUR CHILDREN.
>> THIS ONE FROM "THE NEW YORK
POST," ENOUGH.
REALLY DISCUSSING THE
PRESIDENT'S PLEA THAT WE JUST
CAN'T TOLERATE THIS ANYMORE.
>> SPEAKING FOR THE COUNTRY
THERE.
ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
WE'LL BE BACK WITH MORE AFTER
THIS.
ladies!
oks good
Jack!
Come on,
stop the car.
JACK!
No, no, no, no, no!
The only thing more surprising
than finding the
perfect gifts..
Niice.
...is where you find them.
How did you know?
I had a little help.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
[ Male Announcer ] EVERY TIME
YOU SAY NO TO A CIGARETTE
YOU CELEBRATE A LITTLE WIN.
NICORETTE GUM HELPS CALM
YOUR CRAVINGS
AND MAKES YOU LESS IRRITABLE.
QUIT ONE CIGARETTE AT A TIME.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
>>> UP NEXT, REMEMBERING THE
VICTIMS OF SANDY.
PRESIDENT OBAMA HONORS EACH OF
THE VICTIMS AT A MEMORIAL WHILE
THE FIRST FUNERAL GETS UNDERWAY
THIS MORNING.
>> I'M MIKE NICCO, TRACKING
LIGHT RAIN AND BIG STORM ON THE
WAY IN THE ACCU SEVEN DAY
FORECAST.
>> AND TALK ABOUT PRICE SQUEEZE.
A MAN SPENT HIS NIGHT IN A
CHIMNEY IN SAN FRANCISCO.
JOIN US COM
AND VIDEOS TAKEN FROM HIS HOME
WILL REVEAL THE MOTIVE.
>>> FINALLY THIS MORNING, AN
OUTPOURING OF GRIEF AND SUPPORT
IN THE FACE OF SENSELESS
VIOLENCE.
>> THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, HAVE BANDED
TOGETHER SINCE THE SHOOTING AND
OTHER AMERICANS ARE SO MOVED BY
THE TRAGEDY, THEY'RE FINDING
THEIR OWN WAY TO LEND A HAND.
ONCE AGAIN, HERE'S ABC'S LARA
SPENCER.
♪
>> Reporter: ON A COLD, CRISP,
NEW ENGLAND NIGHT, RESIDENTS
GATHERED AT MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS
ALL OVER TOWN, TRYING TO MAKE
SENSE OF THE IMPOSSIBLE.
>> I'M JUST WAITING TO WAKE UP
FROM THIS NIGHTMARE.
>> Reporter: THEY WERE JOINED BY
HUNDREDS OF STRANGERS WHO
TRAVELED FAR AND WIDE TRYING TO
HELP.
WHY DID YOU NEED TO BE HERE?
>> I'M A MOTHER.
I'M A MOTHER.
>> Reporter: A MOTHER FROM NEW
YORK CITY.
A CHAPLAIN FROM NORTH CAROLINA.
HOW IMPORTANT IS IT TO GIVE BACK
TO THIS COMMUNITY?
>> I HAVE GRANDSONS EXACTLY THE
SAME AGE OF THE VICTIMS.
MY HEART WAS -- I JUST WAS
MOVED.
>> Reporter: THIS FIRE HOUSE IS
NOW THE SITE OF 26 CHRISTMAS
TREES, ONE FOR EACH SOUL TAKEN
AT SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
EACH ONE DONATED BY A WOMAN FROM
NORTH CAROLINA, AND NESTLED WITH
TEDDY BEARS.
HOW IS CHRISTMAS GOING TO BE?
>> UM -- IT'S NOT GOING TO FEEL
LIKE CHRISTMAS.
I THINK, YOU KNOW, IT'S
IMPORTANT TO KEEP THINGS AS
NORMAL AS POSSIBLE FOR EVERYONE.
IT'S ABOUT GIVING.
AND LOVING.
AND KINDNESS.
>> Reporter: RANDOM ACTS OF
KINDNESS ABOUND.
TAKE MICHAEL, OFFERING UP HIS
BULLDOG FOR FREE HUGS AT A LOCAL
COFFEE SHOP.
AMANDA IS A GRIEF COUNSELOR WHO
LIVES AN HOUR AWAY.
SHE'S DONATING TIME TO THOSE
HERE WHO NEED HER MOST.
>> I FEEL LIKE MY HEART HAS BEEN
LIFTED BY THE GOOD COMING IN
FROM ACROSS THE COUNTRY AND
ACROSS THE WORLD.
A TRULY INCREDIBLE EXPERIENCE.
>> THANKS TO LARA SPENCER FOR
THAT.
>>> AND TODAY, WE LAUNCH A
CONVERSATION HERE AT ABC NEWS,
ON EVERY ONE OF OUR PROGRAMS,
AND AT ABCNEWS.COM.
>> STARTING ON "GMA," WE'LL OPEN
UP A DIALOGUE ABOUT GUNS AND
MENTAL ILLNESS AND WHAT CAN BE
DONE TO STOP THE VIOLENCE.
TRAGEDY AT SANDY HOOK, THE
SEARCH F
>>> ITS MONDAY MORNING, 4:30.
THANKS FOR JOINING US.
I'M KRISTEN SZE.
>> I'M ERIC THOMAS.
LIGHT RAIN BUT IT COULD BE
PROBLEM FOR THE MORNING COMMUTE.
>> WE DO HAVE SLICK STREETS OUT
THERE.
NO MATTER WHERE YOU DO NOT SEE
RADAR, IT DID RAIN DURING THE
OVERNIGHT HOURS.
BEST RETURNS ARE COMING FROM
OVER ON THE EAST BAY, THE
PENINSULA DOWN INTO THE SOUTH
BAY, AROUND THE SANTA CRUZ
MOUNTAINS.
YOU CAN SEE RIGHT WHERE 580