THERE IS A MAN INSIDE.
AND YOU'LL NEVER BELIEVE WHO
RACED TO HIS RESCUE.
>>> AND, AN UNPRECEDENTED LIVE
EVENT.
AN AMERICAN HERO JUST HOME FROM
THE FRONT LINES.
WE HAS NO IDEA WE'VE FLOWN HIS
FAMILY TO HIS BASE REUNITE WITH
HIM THIS MORNING.
THEY ARE RIGHT THERE,
SIDE-BY-SIDE, BUT DON'T KNOW IT.
THE EMOTIONAL REUNION ABOUT TO
PLAY OUT LIVE ON "GMA."
>>> GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE.
HAPPY FRIDAY TO ROBIN AT HOME.
WELCOME BACK TO AMY.
RACHEL SMITH IN FOR LARA TODAY.
AND WHAT A SPECIAL SURPRISE WE
HAVE THIS MORNING.
THERE IS OUR AMERICAN HERO.
WITH ALL HIS FRIENDS,
CAPTAIN GERARDO GARCIA.
HE'S BEEN SERVING IN
AFGHANISTAN.
HE'S BEEN GONE FROM HIS FAMILY
FOR MONTHS.
HE THINKS HE'S GOING TO GIVE A
SHOUTOUT TO HIS FELLOW TROOPS IN
AFGHANISTAN AND IRAQ.
THERE'S HIS FAMILY RIGHT THERE.
ANDREA AND HIS THREE, LITTLE
KIDS.
HE HAS NO IDEA HE'S GOING TO BE
REUNITED WITH THEM THIS MORNING.
AND WE CANNOT WAIT.
>> THEY CAN'T HEAR THE SHOW
RIGHT NOW.
>> EXACTLY.
>> DON'T TEXT THEM.
NOBODY LET THEM KNOW.
>> WE'RE GOING TO GET TO THAT.
>>> WE HAVE A LOT OF BREAKING
NEWS OVERNIGHT.
INCLUDING, YOU KNOW,
AS THE CRISIS IN SYRIA
ESCALATES, THE U.S. IS SPENDING
PATRIOT MISSILES AND TROOPS TO
THE SYRIAN BORDER WITH TURKEY.
RIGHT NOW, MARTHA RADDATZ WILL
BE HERE WITH MORE ON THAT.
>>> AND BARBARA WALTERS,
BRINGING US HER EXCLUSIVE WITH
THE PRESIDENT AND FIRST LADY.
THEY RARELY APPEAR TOGETHER FOR
AN INTERVIEW.
BUT THEY DID FOR BARBARA.
WE'LL HEAR THEIR MESSAGE,
SPECIAL MESSAGE FOR ROBIN.
>>> LET'S GET RIGHT TO JOSH
ELLIOTT FOR THE PAIR OF POWERFUL
EARTHQUAKES OFF THE COAST OF
CALIFORNIA.
>>> A POWERFUL EARTHQUAKING
RATTLING BUILDINGS AND NERVES IN
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA.
6.3 MAGNITUDE OFF THE COAST.
>> WE'RE HERE IN PASADENA WHERE
THEY'RE WATCHING THIS ACTIVITY
VERY CLOSELY.
THIS WAS A PRETTY BIG SHAKER.
6.3 IN MAGNITUDE.
IT OCCURRED IN THE PACIFIC
OCEAN.
LOT OF FOLKS HERE IN SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA FELT IT, THOUGH, IT
WAS A PRETTY GOOD JOLT.
FORTUNATELY NO REPORTS OF DAMAGE
OR INJURIES SO FAR.
BACK TO YOU, JOSH.
>> JOHN, THANK YOU.
>>> PEOPLE SHAKEN BY THE QUAKE
TWE
TWEETED IT ON TWITTER.
>>> ALSO THIS MORNING, NEW
PRESSURE ON CONGRESS TO APPROVE
A CRITICAL $60 BILLION AID
PACKAGE FOR VICTIMS OF HURRICANE
SANDY.
THE GOVERNORS OF NEW YORK, NEW
JERSEY AND CONNECTICUT WANT THAT
PACKAGE APPROVED BEFORE THE
HOLIDAY BREAK.
MORE THAN 100 CEOs, ALSO CALLING
ON LAWMAKERS TO ACT QUICKLY.
NEARLY SEVEN WEEKS AFTER THE
STORM STRUCK, MANY VICTIMS ARE
STILL WAITING FOR FUNDS TO
REPAIR THEIR HOMES.
>>> AND IN PHILADELPHIA, THE
HUNT IS ON FOR TWO TEENS AFTER A
DISPUTE OVER AN NBA GAME ENDED
IN GUNFIRE ON A TRAIN.
THIS IS TOUGH TO WATCH.
BUT THE VIDEO CAPTURES A
CONFRONTATION BETWEEN THE TWO,
BELIEVED TO BE 76ers FANS AND A
CHICAGO FAN IN A BULLS JERSEY.
ONE OF THE TEENS PULLS A GUN AND
SHOOTS THE MAN IN THE STOMACH.
YOU SEE IT THERE.
THE SAME BULLET WOULD THEN
STRIKE ANOTHER MAN IN THE LEG.
THANKFULLY, BOTH SHOOTING
VICTIMS ARE EXPECTED TO BE OKAY.
>>> AND SOME ASTONISHING VIDEO
JUST IN, AS WELL, OF A YOUNG
GIRL IN A WHEELCHAIR.
HARD TO WATCH.
SCARED AND IN TEARS, AFTER BEING
DETAINED BY TSA AT DALLAS-FT.
WORTH AIRPORT.
SCREENERS SAY THE 12-YEAR-OLD,
SHELBY WALTERS' PALMS, TESTED
POSITIVE FOR EXPLOSIVES, WHICH
MAY ACTUALLY HAVE BEEN
FERTILIZER TRANSFERRED FROM HER
WHEELCHAIR.
THE GIRL'S MOTHER SAID WHEN IT
COMES TO KIDS, SCREENERS SHOULD
USE COMMON SENSE.
WE DO HOPE SHE'S OKAY.
>>> ALSO, THE iPHONE 5
NOW OFFICIALLY ON SALE IN CHINA.
BUT TODAY'S LAUNCH, NOTHING LIKE
THIS ONE IN JANUARY.
RIOTS BREAKING OUT WHEN THE 4S
WAS RELEASED.
APPLE, HOPING TODAY'S LAUNCH
COULD SINGLE-HANDEDLY STOP ITS
RECENT STOCK SLIDE.
>>> AND, FINALLY,
IT'S NOT YOUR AVERAGE BOTTLE OF
BEER.
THIS IS YOUR CHANCE TO BUY WHAT
IS CONSIDERED THE WORLD'S VERY
BEST BEER.
IT IS CALLED WESTVLETEREN.
>> THAT WAS GOOD.
>> I'M NOT A TRAPIST MONK IN
BELGIUM.
THE BEER BEING SOLD IN THE U.S.
FOR THE FIRST AND POSSIBLY ONLY
TIME.
GOOD LUCK FINDING IT.
AND IF YOU'VE GOT A COOL $85, IT
WILL BUY YOU A SIX-PACK.
>> WOW.
>> MAYBE IF YOU DRINK IT, YOU
CAN SAY IT REALLY WELL, TOO.
>> SERIOUSLY.
MAYBE THEY NAMED IT AFTER THEY
SAMPLED IT.
>>> A LOT OF NEWS TO GET TO.
WE HAVE THAT DRAMATIC WITHDRAWAL
LATE THURSDAY.
U.N. AMBASSADOR
SUSAN RICE TAKES HERSELF OUT OF
THE RUNNING TO REPLACE HILLARY
CLINTON AS SECRETARY OF STATE.
ABC'S JAKE TAPPER IS TRACKING
THE LATEST FROM THE WHITE HOUSE.
GOOD MORNING, JAKE.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING,
GEORGE.
WHITE HOUSE OFFICIALS SAY
THEY'RE ANGRY ABOUT THE UNFAIR
WAY THAT SUSAN RICE WAS TREATED
BY REPUBLICANS ON THE HILL.
WITH SIGNALS FROM REPUBLICANS
THAT HERS WOULD BE A BRUISING
CONFIRMATION BATTLE, AND FROM
THE WHITE HOUSE THAT THE
PRESIDENT THOUGHT SENATOR JOHN
KERRY MIGHT BE A BETTER CHOICE,
OVERNIGHT, THE U.S. AMBASSADOR
TO THE UNITED NATIONS ROLLED OUT
HER WITHDRAWAL CAMPAIGN.
>> I DIDN'T WANT TO SEE A
CONFIRMATION PROCESS THAT WAS
VERY PROLONGED, VERY
POLITICIZED, VERY DISTRACTING
AND VERY DISRUPTIVE.
>> Reporter: ON NBC AND IN A
"WASHINGTON POST" OP-ED, SUSAN
SAID A PARTISAN BATTLE WAS THE
LAST THING THAT THE COUNTRY
NEEDS.
LATE THURSDAY, PRESIDENT OBAMA
RECONFIRMED HIS CONFIDENCE IN
HER.
>> SHE'S DONE AN OUTSTANDING
JOB.
I COULD NOT BE PROUDER WITH HER.
SHE WILL CONTINUE TO BE ONE OF
THE TOP MEMBERS OF MY NATIONAL
SECURITY TEAM.
>> Reporter: RICE HAD BECOME THE
DESIGNATED OBAMA ADMINISTRATION
TARGET FOR REPUBLICANS SEEKING
ANSWERS AND/OR POLITICAL
ADVANTAGE, RELATING TO THE
TERRORIST ATTACKS ON SEPTEMBER
11th, 2012, ON THE DIPLOMATIC
COMPOUND IN BENGHAZI, LIBYA.
>> IN FACT, WHAT THIS BEGAN AS
WAS A SPONTANEOUS, NOT A
PREMEDITATED RESPONSE.
>> Reporter: FIVE DAYS AFTER
THOSE ATTACKS, RICE WENT ON THE
SUNDAY SHOWS, REPEATING TALKING
POINTS FROM THE INTELLIGENCE
COMMUNITY, THAT CRITICS SAID
DOWNPLAYED THE TERRORIST ATTACK
IN THE WEEKS LEADING UP TO THE
ELECTION.
>> I DIDN'T MISLEAD.
I DIDN'T MISREPRESENT.
I DID THE BEST WITH THE
INFORMATION THE UNITED STATES
GOVERNMENT HAD AT THE TIME.
>> Reporter: DEMOCRATS POINT OUT
THAT REPUBLICANS DIDN'T HAVE AS
HARD A TIME WITH A DIFFERENT
NATIONAL SECURITY ADVISER NAMED
RICE WHO HAD DIFFERENT
INACCURATE TALKING POINTS FROM
THE INTELLIGENCE COMMUNITY.
THAT WAS CONDOLEEZZA RICE,
TALKING ABOUT IRAQI WEAPONS OF
MASS DESTRUCTION THAT DIDN'T
EXIST.
THAT WAS A DIFFERENT TIME.
GEORGE?
>> YES, IT WAS, JAKE, THANKS
VERY MUCH.
>>> LET'S GET MORE ON THIS FROM
OUR SENIOR FOREIGN AFFAIRS
CORRESPONDENT, MARTHA RADDATZ.
AND MARTHA RADDATZ, NOW IN LINE
TO BE NAMED SECRETARY OF STATE,
SENATOR JOHN KERRY OF
MASSACHUSETTS.
HE'S LIKELY TO BE EASILY
CONFIRMED.
BUT THIS IS STILL A PAINFUL,
PERSONAL RETREAT FOR BOTH THE
PRESIDENT AND AMBASSADOR RICE.
>> Reporter: IT'S TRUE, GEORGE.
YOU KNOW,
THEY'RE VERY DIFFERENT KINDS OF
CHOICES, VERY DIFFERENT KINDS OF
STYLE.
KERRY'S SAFE, LOW-KEY,
EVEN-KEELED AND HAS LOTS OF
EXPERIENCE.
SUSAN RICE HAS LOTS OF
EXPERIENCE IN FOREIGN AFFAIRS.
BUT SHE'S FAR MORE COMBATIVE AND
IN YOUR FACE.
SHE WAS SEEN AS A RISKIER
CHOICE.
AND RIGHT NOW, THE PRESIDENT
DOESN'T WANT TO BATTLE OVER
PEOPLE.
HE'LL BATTLE OVER POLICY, BUT
NOT PEOPLE.
>> THAT'S WHAT THE AMBASSADOR
SAID, AS WELL.
THAT'S WHY SHE PULLED HERSELF
OUT.
MEANWHILE, WE'RE SEEING THE
CHALLENGES CONTINUE TO MOUNT FOR
THE PRESIDENT OVERSEAS,
ESPECIALLY IN SYRIA.
THAT CRISIS CONTINUING TO
ESCALATE.
WE LEARNED OVERNIGHT THAT THE
UNITED STATES WILL BE SENDING
MORE FIREPOWER TO THE REGION.
>> Reporter: THEY WILL.
TWO PATRIOT ROUNDS TO PREVENT
ROUNDS FROM CROSSING THE BOARD
WITH TURKEY.
THAT'S HAPPENED IN THE PAST.
BUT THIS IS REALLY A SYMBOLIC
SHOW OF FORCE, TO SIGNAL SUPPORT
OF TURKEY AND TO PUT MORE
PRESSURE ON SYRIA.
BUT IT DOES REQUIRE ABOUT 400
TROOPS TO OPERATE THOSE SYSTEMS.
THAT WILL TAKE A LITTLE WHILE TO
GET THERE, GEORGE.
>> OKAY, MARTHA RADDATZ, THANKS
VERY MUCH.
>>> LET'S STAY IN WASHINGTON NOW
AND MOVE ON TO THE LATEST ON THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
JUST 18 DAYS BEFORE EVERYONE'S
TAXES GO UP.
EVERY FEDERAL PROGRAM SET TO BE
CUT.
ABC'S JON KARL COVERS THAT FOR
US FROM CAPITOL HILL.
AND, JON, THE PRESIDENT AND
HOUSE SPEAKER BOEHNER MET AGAIN
LAST NIGHT.
IT WAS LESS THAN AN HOUR.
AND IT DOESN'T LOOK LIKE THEY'RE
MAKING MUCH PROGRESS.
>> Reporter: NO, NOT AT ALL.
NO SIGNS OF PROGRESS AT ALL UP
HERE, GEORGE.
BOTH SIDES EMERGED FROM THAT
MEETING, CALLING IT FRANK.
NOW, YOU KNOW IN INTERNATIONAL
POLITICS, WHEN THE SIDES
DESCRIBE A MEETING AS FRANK, IT
USUALLY MEANS THEY VEHEMENTLY
DISAGREED OR THEY'RE ON THE
VERGE OF WAR.
I TALKED TO A PROMINENT HOUSE
DEMOCRAT LATE LAST NIGHT WHO
TOLD ME, SIMPLY, GET YOUR
PARACHUTE READY.
WE'RE GOING OVER THE CLIFF.
MEANWHILE, I CAN TELL YOU,
GEORGE, CONGRESS IS PRETTY MUCH,
YOU KNOW, A DESERT RIGHT NOW.
BOTH CONGRESSIONAL LEADERS ON
BOTH SIDES OF THE CAPITOL GOING
HOME FOR THE WEEKEND.
NO SIGNS OF REALLY ANYTHING
GOING ON HERE.
>> AS WE'RE CLOSING IN, JUST 18
DAYS TO GO,
I WOULD IMAGINE THAT BOTH SIDES
MUST HAVE FALLBACK PLANS IN
PLACE IF THERE'S NOT GOING TO BE
A DEAL.
>> Reporter: WELL, CERTAINLY, NO
PROSPECTS OF A MAJOR DEFICIT
DEAL.
ONE KIND OF A FALLBACK PLAN,
REPUBLICANS ARE TALKING ABOUT,
IS THAT THEY WOULD AGREE TO
EXTEND WHATEVER TAX CUTS THEY
CAN.
THAT MEANS THE MIDDLE-CLASS TAX
CUTS THE PRESIDENT WANTS TO
EXTEND.
BUT DO NOTHING ELSE.
THAT MEANS A BIG BATTLE OVER THE
DEBT CEILING COMING IN THE EARLY
PART OF THE YEAR.
>> OKAY, JON KARL, THANKS VERY
MUCH.
>>> OF COURSE, WE'RE GOING TO
COVER ALL THESE WASHINGTON
STORIES, THE WHOLE WEEK IN
POLITICS, SUNDAY ON "THIS WEEK,"
WITH SENATOR JOHN McCAIN AND THE
ROUNDTABLES.
>>> AND GUESS WHAT, JUST TWO
WEEKENDS UNTIL CHRISTMAS.
SO MANY PEOPLE KOUMPBTING DOWN
TO THE HOLIDAYS.
AND IT COULD BE A RECORD-SETTING
HOLIDAY FOR BOTH RETAIL AND
TRAVEL.
ABC'S BIANNA GOLODRYGA IS
STANDING BY WITH THE EXTREMES
RETAILERS ARE GOING THROUGH TO
GET YOUR DOLLARS.
BUT LET'S FIRST GO TO LISA
STARK, WHO IS TRACKING THE
LATEST ON WHY THIS HOLIDAY COULD
BE VERY TRICKY FOR TRAVELING.
LISA, GOOD MORNING.
>> Reporter: AMY, TRAVELING OVER
THE HOLIDAYS IS BEST
CIRCUMSTANCES.
CAN BE TRICKY.
GET A LOAD OF THIS.
HUNDREDS OF WORKERS AT NEW YORK
CITY JFK AIRPORT THREATENING TO
GO ON STRIKE ON DECEMBER 20th.
THESE ARE THE SECURITY GUARDS.
NONE AT THE CHECKPOINT.
BUT THEY DIRECT TRAFFIC, MAKE
SURE THE GATES ARE SECURE.
IT COULD ADD TO THE CHAOS OF
TRAVELERS WILL FEEL OVER A BUSY
HOLIDAY.
PLANES WILL BE PACKED.
THE AIRLINE TRADE GROUP SAYS 85%
TO 90% OF THE SEATS WILL BE
FILLED.
AND THE HOLIDAY TRIP WILL COST
YOU MORE THAN LAST YEAR, 9%
MORE, ACCORDING TO
TRAVELOCITY.
NONSTOP PRICES ARE NEARLY DOUBLE
THAN WHAT THEY WERE AT THE
BEGINNING OF DECEMBER.
>> THE AVERAGE PRICE
IS OVER $400 ROUND-TRIP.
THAT'S A BIG BITE OUT OF
SOMEONE'S WALLET, ESPECIALLY IF
YOU MULTIPLY THAT ACROSS SEVERAL
FAMILY MEMBERS.
>> Reporter: IF YOU'RE STILL ON
THE FENCE ABOUT WHETHER TO TAKE
THAT CHRISTMAS FLIGHT, DECIDE
FAST.
>> THE TIME TO BOOK WAS WEEKS
AGO.
BUT IF YOU HAVEN'T BOOKED YET,
YOU HAVE TO PULL THE TRIGGER
RIGHT NOW.
PRICES ARE GOING UP, NOT EVERY
DAY, BUT EVERY HOUR YOU WAIT.
>> Reporter: LOOKING FOR CHEAPER
FARES, TRAVELOCITY SAYS YOUR
BEST BET IS CHRISTMAS EVE AND
CHRISTMAS DAY.
THE MOST EXPENSIVE DAYS TO FLY
ARE DECEMBER 21st AND 22nd, AND
RETURNING ON DECEMBER 30th.
THAT COULD COST YOU AN EXTRA
$500 A TICKET.
AND IF YOU CAN BE FLEXIBLE,
THERE ARE LESS EXPENSIVE
DESTINATIONS, THINK FLORIDA,
DENVER AND LOS ANGELES.
ALL BECAUSE OF FIERCE AIRLINE
COMPETITION.
CONNECTING FLIGHTS ARE OFTEN
CHEAPER AS ARE THOSE SHORT HOPS
OF LESS THAN AN HOUR.
AND BE CAREFUL HOW YOU PACK YOUR
BAGS.
TOO MANY OF THEM OR TOO HEAVY,
AND THOSE BAG FEES CAN COST YOU
MORE THAN THE TICKET.
AND IF YOU'RE SKIPPING THE PLANE
AND TRAVELING BY CAR, THAT'S
THE ROADS MAY BE BUSIER THAN
THEY'VE BEEN IN SOME SIX YEARS.
ALL BECAUSE GASOLINE PRICES HAVE
PLUMMETED.
IT'S A DOLLAR LESS A GALLON THAN
IT WAS JUST A YEAR AGO.
AT LEAST, AMY, THAT IS A VERY
NICE CHRISTMAS PRESENT.
>> MORE MONEY FOR SHOPPING.
THANKS SO MUCH.
>>> SPEAKING OF SHOPPING, RETAIL
SALES ROSE IN NOVEMBER.
AND DECEMBER COULD BE AN EVEN
BIGGER MONTH FOR THE ECONOMY, AS
RETAILERS COMPETE FOR YOUR
MONEY.
ABC'S BIANNA GOLODRYGA IS
TRACKING THE LATEST.
THEY'RE PULLING OUT ALL THE
STOPS.
>> Reporter: THEY ARE, AMY.
THE HOLIDAY SHOPPING SEASON
STARTED OFF WITH A BANG.
REMEMBER THIS --
THANKSGIVING WEEKEND, AMERICANS
SPENT SOME $59 BILLION.
THAT'S UP NEARLY 13% FROM LAST
YEAR.
NOW, THE CHALLENGE IS TO KEEP
THE MOMENTUM GOING.
KEEP SHOPPERS IN THE STORES.
HOW ARE STORES DOING THAT?
THEY'RE EXTENDING HOURS, MAKING
IT EASIER FOR SHOPPERS TO COME
OVER AND BUY MERCHANDISE.
MACY'S, FOR EXAMPLE, OPEN
48 HOURS THE WEEKEND BEFORE
CHRISTMAS.
TARGET, OPEN UNTIL 9:00 P.M. ON
CHRISTMAS EVE.
AND THEN, RIGHT ACROSS THE
STREET AT TOYS "R" US HERE, FOR
THREE WEEKS THEY'RE OPENED
24 HOURS AROUND THE CLOCK.
THIS IS GOOD FOR THE SHOPPERS
AND FOR THE ECONOMY THAT MORE
TEMPORARY JOBS WILL BE ADDED.
SOME 619,000 JOBS WERE CREATED
IN OCTOBER AND NOVEMBER ALONE.
THAT'S UP SINCE LAST YEAR.
AND UP 19% FROM LAST YEAR.
NEARLY TO A 2000 HIGH.
AMY.
>> GOOD NEWS.
THANKS FOR THAT.
>>> BACK TO BARBARA WALTERS FOR
MORE OF HER EXCLUSIVE INTERVIEW
WITH PRESIDENT OBAMA AND THE
FIRST LADY.
IT'S BECOMING A HOLIDAY
TRADITION.
IT AIRS TONIGHT ON "20/20."
AND BARBARA IS HERE WITH SOME OF
THE HIGHLIGHTS RIGHT NOW.
YOU GOT THE FULL TOUR.
AS ALWAYS.
>> I GOT THE FULL TOUR OF THE
WHITE HOUSE, WITH THE STAR OF
THE WHITE HOUSE.
THAT'S NOT THE PRESIDENT OR THE
FIRST LADY.
YOU KNOW IT'S BO.
>> BUT YOU DID SIT DOWN WITH THE
PRESIDENT AND COVERED THE NEWS
OF THE DAY, AS WELL?
>> WE DID.
WE TALKED TO THE TWO OF THEM.
THEY'RE VERY DIFFERENT WHEN THEY
ARE TOGETHER.
THEY'RE FUNNY AND CUTE.
BUT WE ALSO ASKED THE PRESIDENT
A VERY IMPORTANT QUESTION
ABOUT THE LEGALIZATION OF
MARIJUANA.
THERE ARE TWO STATES IN WHICH IT
IS LEGAL.
>> WASHINGTON AND COLORADO.
WE'LL TAKE A LOOK.
>> DO YOU THINK THAT MARIJUANA
SHOULD BE LEGALIZED?
>> I WOULDN'T GO THAT FAR.
BUT I WHAT THINK IS THAT, AT
THIS POINT, WASHINGTON AND
COLORADO, YOU'VE SEEN THE VOTERS
SPEAK ON THIS ISSUE.
AND, AS IT IS, THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT HAS A LOT TO DO WHEN
IT COMES TO CRIMINAL
PROSECUTIONS.
IT DOES NOT MAKE SENSE FROM A
PRIORITIZATION POINT OF VIEW,
FOR US TO FOCUS ON RECREATIONAL
DRUG USERS IN A STATE THAT HAS
ALREADY SAID, UNDER STATE LAW,
THAT'S LEGAL.
>> THAT'S INTERESTING.
THE PRESIDENT DOESN'T WANT TO
CONFLICT WITH THE STATES.
EVEN THOUGH IT'S THE ATTORNEY
GENERAL'S FINAL DECISION.
>> I ASKED HIM ABOUT THE FACT
THAT WHEN HE WAS YOUNGER, HE
SMOKES MARIJUANA.
AND WHAT DOES HE TELL HIS GIRLS?
HE SAYS, DON'T MAKE THE MISTAKES
THAT I MADE.
>> THE ONLY THING HE CAN SAY.
YOU ALSO TALKED TO THE PRESIDENT
ABOUT HOW HE'S SPENDING THAT
LITTLE BIT OF SPARE TIME HE HAS?
>> AND YOU SEE THE TWO OF THEM
TOGETHER, QUARRELLING ABOUT
SCRABBLE, NO LESS.
TAKE A LOOK.
YOU HAVE AN iPAD.
>> I DO.
>> WHAT'S YOUR FAVORITE APP?
>> SCRABBLE.
>> OH, YEAH.
GOSH.
SOMETIMES I WANT TO YANK THAT
OUT OF YOUR HAND.
>> AND WHO WINS?
>> HE'S GOOD AT SCRABBLE.
HE'S VERY IRRITATING.
>> SHE DOESN'T LIKE LOSING.
SO, SHE STOPPED PLAYING.
>> I DON'T LIKE LOSING TO YOU
BECAUSE YOU'RE IRRITATING WHEN
YOU WIN.
>> THE THING THAT'S CHARMING
ABOUT THIS INTERVIEW, WHICH
YOU'LL SEE TONIGHT, IS HOW
DIFFERENT THEY ARE -- YOU KNOW,
WHEN YOU INTERVIEW THEM ALONE,
THEY'RE VERY SERIOUS.
TOGETHER, SHE TEASES HIM.
HE TEASES HER.
IT'S A WHOLE OTHER LOOK.
BUT THEN, WHAT I FOUND VERY
TOUCHING, I ASKED THE PRESIDENT
AND FIRST LADY IF THEY HAD A
MESSAGE FOR ROBIN.
AND, INDEED, THEY DID.
>> LET'S TAKE A LOOK.
>> I WANT TO MAKE SURE TO SEND A
BIG CHRISTMAS GREETING TO ROBIN
ROBERTS, PART OF YOUR TEAM.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> WHO IS JUST SUCH A WONDERFUL
PERSON.
SOMEBODY THAT WE'VE, YOU KNOW,
COME TO REALLY LOVE.
SO, WE'RE JUST ROOTING FOR HER.
HOPE SHE'S DOING GREAT.
AND WANT HER TO KNOW THAT THE
WHOLE OBAMA CREW IS THINKING
ABOUT HER.
>> YEAH.
ROBIN, WE LOVE YOU.
WE WANT ROBIN TO COME BACK AND
KEEP DOING GREAT THINGS.
>> AMEN TO THAT.
THAT'S FANTASTIC RIGHT THERE.
NOW, THEY WERE PART OF THE
INTERVIEW.
YOU ALSO GOT TO TALK ABOUT MALIA
AND SASHA, AS WELL.
>> WELL, MALIA HAS GOTTEN A CELL
PHONE.
AND THE PRESIDENT SAID, ONE OF
THE REASONS THAT -- HE SAYS ONE
OF THE REASONS I'M GLAD THAT I
WAS RE-ELECTED IS, I HAVE THE
SECRET SERVICE TO KEEP AN EYE ON
THE GIRLS, ESPECIALLY NOW THAT
MALIA IS GETTING OLD ENOUGH FOR
BOYS TO BE CALLING.
THEY USED TO HAVE TO CALL
THROUGH THE WHITE HOUSE.
NOW, SHE HAS HER OWN CELL PHONE.
>> THAT IS A BIG STEP.
HOW OLD IS MALIA NOW?
>> 14.
BY THE TIME THIS TERM FINISHES,
SHE WILL BE 18, READY FOR
COLLEGE.
AND CERTAINLY READY FOR DATING.
SO, YOU KNOW,
THEY TALKED A LITTLE ABOUT THE
CHANGES IN THEIR LIVES.
THERE'S NO GROUND RULES ABOUT
THE CELL PHONE.
BUT MRS. OBAMA SAYS, SHE NEVER
KNOWS WHEN I'M GOING TO WALK
INTO HER ROOM AND SEE WHAT SHE'S
TEXTING.
PARENTS ARE PARENTS, NO MATTER
WHAT.
>> NO QUESTION ABOUT IT.
WE CAN'T WAIT TO SEE ALL OF IT
TONIGHT.
THANK YOU, BARBARA, ON "20/20."
CHRISTMAS AT THE WHITE HOUSE, AT
10:00, 9:00 CENTRAL, RIGHT HERE
ON ABC.
>>> NOW, LET'S GO TO SAM FOR THE
WEATHER.
>> WE'RE GOING TO START WITH
PICTURES OUT OF SAN DIEGO.
JUST FINISHED
THEIR WETTEST DAY IN TWO YEARS.
GETTING AN INCH AND A HALF IN
RAIN IN SAN DIEGO, DOESN'T SOUND
LIKE A LOT TO A LOT OF FOLKS.
BUT THAT'S THEIR MONTHLY TOTAL
FOR DECEMBER.
THAT'S THEIR AVERAGE.
THREE INCHES OF RAIN AROUND THAT
SAN DIEGO AREA.
AND IT'S ONE, TWO, THREE WET
SYSTEMS THAT MOVE ACROSS THE
COASTLINE, DROPPING DOWN AND
MOVING ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
THAT'S THE ONE THAT MOVED
THROUGH YESTERDAY.
THIS IS TONIGHT'S.
AND THEN THERE'S ANOTHER ONE
THAT COMES THROUGH BY THE TIME
WE GET TO SATURDAY NIGHT.
THAT PUTS A LOT OF MOISTURE
ACROSS THE MIDDLE OF THE COUNTRY
FOR THIS WEEKEND.
WE SEE THE PATTERN CONTINUING
INTO NET WEEK.
BE READY FOR BIG HITS OF RAIN.
AND SOME OF THE RAIN WILL BE ONE
TO TWO INCHES.
AND LOOK AT THIS LINE NORTH.
THAT COULD BE A LITTLE ICY MESS
THROUGH THAT REGION, AS WELL.
MOST OF THIS STORM SYSTEM IS
WARM.
BUT COULD BE SOME ICY SPOTS.
HOW GORGEOUS IT IS ON THE EAST
COAST TODAY AND TOMORROW.
>>  WE'LL GO THROUGH ALL OF
AMERICA'S WEATHER IN THE NEXT
HALF HOUR.
IT'S AN AWFUL LOT OF RAIN MOVING
ACROSS THE COUNTRY THIS WEEKEND.
AMY.
>> SAM, THANKS SO MUCH.
>>> COMING UP HERE ON "GMA," THE
DRAMT DEVELOPMENTS IN THAT
TRIAL OF THE HIGH SCHOOL
VALEDICTORIAN CHARGED WITH
KILLING HIS OWN MOTHER.
HIS FATHER SPEAKS OUT.
>>> ALSO AHEAD, THE PICKUP
TOSSED INTO THE AIR BY A
TORNADO.
THERE'S A MAN INSIDE FEARING FOR
HIS LIFE.
HE IS OKAY.
BUT WAIT UNTIL YOU HEAR WHO
RACED TO HIS RESCUE.
>>> ALSO, AN UNPRECEDENTED, LIVE
EVENT FOR YOU.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT AN AMERICAN
HERO JUST BACK FROM AFGHANISTAN.
HE HAS NO IDEA, THOUGH, WE FLEW
IN HIS FAMILY.
THEY ARE WAITING NEXT DOOR, AT
HIS BASE,
THE REUNION, LIVE, ONLY ON
"GMA."
GO NOWHERE.
REUNION, LIVE, ONLY ON
"GMA."
GO NOWHERE.
[ Sea ] HI!
THSEA CALLING.
WHEN'S THE LAST TIME
YOU VISITED ME?
WHEN I WENT SURFING.
I LOVE TO SURF.
CAN YOU IMAGINE
SURFING IN THE MIDDLE OF ME?
IN THE MIDDLE OF YOU?
OH YES!
[ giggles ] NICE MOVES!
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
OUR BIGGEST DECEMBER
SALES EVENT EVER.
GOING ON NOW.
CALL 1-800-ROYAL-CARIBBEAN.
HE IS A GOOD LITTLE MONKEY
AND ALWAYS VERY CURIOUS.
ONE DAY GEORGE GOT
AN IMPORTANT LETTER.
HE'S BUILT A ROCKET SHIP
TO TRAVEL INTO SPACE."
GOOGLE, HOW FAR IS EARTH
TO THE MOON?
THE MOON IS 238,900 MILES...
"THE GREAT MOMENT HAD COME."
3, 2, 1...
[ GIGGLING ]
NESPRESSO.
WHERE I NEVER HAVE TO COMPROMISE
ON ANYTHING.
♪
WHERE JUST ONE TOUCH
CREATES THE PERFECT COFFEE.
WHERE EVERY CAPPUCCINO AND LATTE
IS ONLY MADE WITH FRESH MILK.
AND WHERE THE STAFF
IS EXCEPTIONALLY FRIENDLY.
♪
NESPRESSO. WHAT ELSE?
get to Sears Super Saturday,
with Friday preview.
Coats are 19.99,
and save even more with pass.
Get ½ Carat Diamond
earrings for $49.99.
Plus, all Craftsman wrench
sets are on sale.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
HERSHEY'S DROPS.
A LOT OF HERSHEY'S HAPPINESS IN
LITTLE DROPS OF MILK CHOCOLATE.
AND COOKIES N CREME.
PURE HERSHEY'S.
YOU WANNA SEE IF WALMART HAS
SIMILAR GIFTS FOR LESS?
YEAH.
LET'S GO.
SAMSUNG GALAXY S3 --
OVER FIFTY DOLLARS LESS
THAN BEST BUY!
WOW! FIFTY BUCKS!
YEAH!
THAT'S A PAIR OF SHOES.
SEE FOR YOURSELF IF YOU COULD
SAVE ON THE GIFTS YOU WANT.
WALMART.
>> NOW FROM ABC7 NBC, FIRE
INVESTIGATORS HOPE TO GET THEIR
FIRST LOOK INSIDE A GUTTED
MACHINE SHOP IN FREMONT.
THE FIRE ENGULFED C&H
ENTERPRISES YESTERDAY AFTERNOON.
THE FLAMES DESTROYED NEARLY
EVERYTHING INSIDE THE MACHINE
SHOP.
THEY MAKE COMPONENTS USED BY THE
HIGH-TECH INDUSTRY, THE 60
WORKERS ARE WAITING TO HEAR
ABOUT PLANS TO RE-OPEN.
>> AND NOW WHAT IS GOING ON WITH
THE TRAFFIC?
>> NOT A BAD COMMUTE.
A BEAUTIFUL SHOT AS THE SUN IS
COMING UP 80 WESTBOUND FUNNELING
AND 580 LOOKING GOOD, AND YOU DO
HAVE A BIT OF A DELAY THERE.
AND SEMINARY WE HAVE A STALL
BLOCKING THE OFF RAMP, AND
WESTBOUND, AT 5th COMING OFF
THE BAY BRIDGE WE HAVE A STALL
WITH THINGS BACKING UP ON THE
BAY BRIDGE.
>> WHEN WE COME BACK, OUR
METEOROLOGIST AND
>> CHECK OUT THE CLOUD COVER
THIS MORNING OVER THE BAY AREA.
WE CAN SEE THE TOWER OFF IN THE
DISTANCE.
DOPLAR IS SHOWS BLUES AND
GREENS, THE LOWEST THRESHHOLD.
IF WE ARE LUCKY SPRINKLES ARE
MAKING IT TO THE GROUND.
WE ARE IN THE MID-30'S TO
MID-40'S AND ON OUR WAY TO UPPER
40'S TO LOW 50'S WITH SUNSHINE
THIS AFTERNOON AND A STRAY
SHOWER IS POSSIBLE.
WITHOUT THE CLOUDS TONIGHT,
FROST IS POSSIBLE INLAND, TO
AROUND 40 FOR THE BAY.
WE HAVE A BETTER CHANCE OF
MEASURABLE RAIN SATURDAY AND
SUNDAY BUT IT WILL BE VER
[ Female Announcer ]
MARTINELLI'S GOLD MEDAL
SPARKLING CIDER
IS THE PERFECT CHOICE
FOR HOLIDAY GATHERINGS.
MARTINELLI'S IS NON-ALCOHOLIC,
FESTIVE LIKE CHAMPAGNE,
AND TASTES GREAT!
MARTINELLI'S: SINCE 1868.
>>> WE GOT AN AMERICAN HERO
RIGHT THERE.
CAPTAIN GERARDO GARCIA.
RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE RIGHT THERE.
JUST BACK FROM AFGHANISTAN.
THINKS HE'S ABOUT TO GIVE A
SHOUTOUT TO HIS BUDDIES IN
AFGHANISTAN.
WHAT HE DOESN'T KNOW IS THAT
RIGHT IN THE NEXT ROOM ARE HIS
WIFE AND THREE, LITTLE KIDS.
THIS IS GOING TO BE A GREAT
SURPRISE.
THEY CANNOT HEAR US AT ALL.
BUT IN JUST A LITTLE WHILE,
THEY'RE GOING TO BE REUNITED
LIVE, RIGHT HERE ON "GMA."
WE CANNOT WAIT FOR THAT THIS
MORNING.
IT'S GOING TO BE SO GREAT, AMY.
>> I'M SO EXCITED.
AND I LOVE THAT THEY'RE BEING
TOLD TO WAVE.
THEY HAVE NO IDEA WHAT'S GOING
TO HAPPEN NEXT.
WE'RE EXCITED TO BRING THAT TO
YOU.
>>> ALSO AHEAD,
THE PICKUP TRUCK VERSUS THE
TORNADO.
THIS IS INCREDIBLE VIDEO.
HOW COULD ANYONE SURVIVE BEING
TOSSED THROUGH THE AIR LIKE
THAT?
THE DRIVER INSIDE IS REMARKABLY
OKAY.
AND YOU'LL NEVER GUESS WHO RACED
TO HIS RESCUE.
IT CERTAINLY SURPRISED HIM.
>>> AND DETAILS FROM "DANCING
WITH THE STARS" HOST BROOKE
BURKE-CHARVET ABOUT HER
MEDICAL BATTLE.
GOOD NEWS ABOUT HER HEALTH THAT
SHE JUST REVEALED.
IN A BIT.
>>> WE'RE GOING TO GET TO THE
TRIAL OF THE HIGH SCHOOL
VALEDICTORIAN ACCUSED OF KILLING
HIS OWN MOTHER.
IT'S NOW IN CLOSING ARGUMENTS.
AND HIS FATHER IS SPEAKING OUT.
ABC'S JOHN MULLER JOINS US WITH
THE VERY LATEST.
>> Reporter: IN CLOSING
ARGUMENTS, PROSECUTORS TELLING
JURORS THAT THIS MURDER CASE IS
LIKE A PUZZLE AND THEY HAVE ALL
OF THE PIECES TO CONVICT JEFFREY
PYNE OF KILLING HIS MOTHER.
THEY TALK ABOUT HOW THINGS WERE
WRONG IN THAT HOUSE AND HIS
MOTHER WERE VERY SICK.
BUT THEY SAY THAT'S NO EXCUSE
FOR MURDER.
THIS MORNING, JUST BEFORE THE
CASE AGAINST JEFFREY PYNE GOES
TO A JURY, HIS FATHER IS
SPEAKING OUT, IN HIS DEFENSE.
>> IT'S A TOUGH THING TO GO
THROUGH.
ALL I CAN TELL YOU IS THAT, I
KNOW MY SON, AND MY SON WOULD
NEVER HARM HIS MOTHER.
HE JUST WOULD NEVER HARM HER.
>> Reporter: BERNIE PYNE TOLD
REPORTERS OUTSIDE OF COURT
THURSDAY THE CASE AGAINST HIS
SON IS NOT ROOTED IN FACT.
JUST HOURS EARLIER, THE
PROSECUTION SAID THE OPPOSITE IN
THEIR CLOSING ARGUMENTS.
>> WHEN HE'S GOING TO GET THAT
BOARD, YOU CAN INFER FROM THAT
THAT HE HAS THE INTENT TO KILL
HER WHEN HE GOES TO GET THE
BOARD.
THERE'S NO OTHER REASON TO GO
AND GET THAT BOARD.
>> Reporter: TELLING JURORS THE
FORMER HIGH SCHOOL VALEDICTORIAN
HAD BLUDGEONED HIS MOTHER TO
DEATH IN 2011 IN THE FAMILY
GARAGE.
PROSECUTORS SAY RUTH PYNE WAS
MENTALLY ILL AND ABUSED HER SON
FOR YEARS.
>> THE TRIAL HAS BEEN LARGELY
CIRCUMSTANTIAL.
THEY DON'T HAVE ANY PHYSICAL
EVIDENCE.
>> Reporter: WHAT PROSECUTORS
DO HAVE, ARE THESE PHOTOS OF
JEFFREY PYNE'S BLISTERED HANDS,
TAKEN SHORTLY AFTER THE CRIME.
INJURIES PYNE SAYS CAME FROM
THROWING WOODEN STORAGE PALLETS
AT HIS JOB.
>> THEY HAVE HAD A LOT OF
MEDICAL TESTIMONY THAT HIS STORY
HOW THAT HAPPENED IS UNLIKELY.
>> Reporter: THIS MORNING, THE
COMMUNITY TO SUPPORTED THE
22 KWLEERLD BIOLOGY STUDENT
REMAINS SKEPTICAL.
>> I FEEL VERY CONFIDENT THAT
JEFFERY IS INNOCENT AND THAT THE
JURY WILL SEE IT MY WAY ALSO.
>> WE'LL SEE SOON IF JEFFERY
PINE WILL WALK FREE.
AMY.
>> JOHN MULLER, THANKS SO MUCH.
>>> LET'S BRING IN GMA LEGAL
ANALYST DAN ABRAMS.
THEY DON'T HAVE TO PROVE
PREMEDITATION, HOW BIG OF A WIN
IS THIS?
>> THIS IS A HUGE WIN.
THE FACT THAT THIS SECOND-DEGREE
MURDER CHARGE IS NOW ON THE
TABLE, THAT THESE JURORS CAN
COMPROMISE, EXACTLY WHAT THE
DEFENSE IS CONCERNED ABOUT.
THAT'S WHY THE DEFENSE OPPOSED
THIS.
THEY DIDN'T THE OPTION OF
SECOND-DEGREE MURDER.
THEY WANTED TO PROVE
PREMEDITATION.
REAL QUESTIONS ABOUT THE ALIBI.
QUESTIONS ABOUT THE INJURIES ON
HIS HANDS.
BUT PROVING PREMEDITATION HERE
WOULD HAVE BEEN DIFFICULT.
I THINK IT'S VERY UNLIKELY THAT
THERE WILL BE A DEFENSE.
>> WHAT'S THE IMPACT OF THAT?
>> IT'S DEFINITELY, THINK IT'S
AN ADVANTAGE FOR PROSECUTORS.
THEY HAVE TO PUT THE PIECES OF
THE PUZZLE TOGETHER, THE JURORS
DO, FOR THEM TO BASICALLY SPEND
THE NIGHT WITH JUST THE
PROSECUTION'S CLOSING ARGUMENT
IN THEIR MINDS I THINK IS VERY
HELPFUL TO THE PROSECUTION, THE
DEFENSE MAKE ITS CLOSING
ARGUMENT THIS MORNING.
DAN ABRAMS, WE'LL KEEP OUR EYES
ON THIS GEORGE IN.
>>> THAT ASTONISHING PIECE OF
VIDEO THAT SAM FIRST SHOWED YOU
TUESDAY.
SCOOPING UP A TRUCK AND TOSSING
IT ON A NEARBY CAR.
WHAT WE DIDN'T KNOW THEN WAS
SOMEONE WAS INSIDE.
ROB NELSON SHOWS US BY SOME
MIRACLE THAT DRIVER SURVIVED.
>> Reporter: LOOK CLOSELY, THIS
TINY SPECK IS A MASSIVE FORD
PICKUP TRUCK WHILE YOU CAN'T SEE
HIM, JERRY IS INSIDE ON THE RIDE
OF HIS LIFE.
>> I'M THINKING, I'M DEAD.
I JUST SEE ALL THIS.
BUT I'M REALLY DEAD.
>> Reporter: HE WAS MAKING
DELIVERIES WHEN A TORNADO CAME
THROUGH BEFORE SENDING HIS TRUCK
AIRBORNE.
IT SWUNG HIM INTO THE AIR,
SMASHING HIS TRUCK ON TO ANOTHER
ONE PARKED NEARBY.
>> I DON'T KNOW WHERE I WAS.
I COULD FEEL THAT I WAS ROLLING
AND ROCKING.
THIS DRIVER WAS DRIVING IN THE
OPPOSITE DIRECTION.
SHE RACED TO HIS RESCUE.
>> I IMMEDIATELY JUMPED OUT OF
THE TRUCK.
ARE YOU OKAY?
>> Reporter: THERE'S AN EVEN
MORE AMAZING TWIST THAT GOOD
SAMARITAN IS HIS DAUGHTER.
>> I HEARD MY DAUGHTER'S VOICE.
MY BABY GIRL.
WHEN I LOOKED UP, HERE SHE COME
WALKING.
>> HOW DID YOU GET HERE?
HOW DID I KNOW?
>> I SAW THE WHOLE THING
HAPPENING.
>> Reporter: THIS MORNING, HIS
DELIVERY TRUCK IS TOTALLED BUT
HE'S ON THE MEND.
FOR "GOOD MORNING AMERICA," ROB
NELSON, ABC NEWS, NEW YORK.
>> HOME ALIVE AFTER ROLLING AND
ROCKING.
>> ROLLING AND ROCKING.
>> UNBELIEVABLE.
>>> I MEAN THE VIDEO WAS CRAZY
ENOUGH WHEN IT WAS PICKED UP.
TO KNOW SOMEONE WAS INSIDE, WOW.
>>> THE FIRST BIG SNOW OF THE
SEASON, YOU'LL REMEMBER A LOT OF
SKI RESORT HAD TO CLOSE IN
NOVEMBER BECAUSE THERE WASN'T
ANY SNOW, WELL, NOW, THEY ARE
OPENING.
PLENTY OF IT.
OVER THE NEXT COUPLE OF DAYS
INTO THE WEEKEND, AS WE SHOW YOU
THOSE THREE STORMS THAT KIND OF
GLIDE OFF THE WESTERN COAST,
THEIR DROPPING BIG SNOWFALL
TOTALS.
TAHOE, FLAGSTAFF, PICKING UP
SNOW.
NOW WE START TO GET THE MOISTURE
MOVING ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
RIGHT NOW, MILDER TEMPERATURES
INTO THE DEEP SOUTH.
DALLAS BY SATURDAY 74 DEGREES.
NEW ORLEANS, 72 BY THE TIME WE
GET TO SATURDAY.
WE'LL NOTICE, THOUGH, A BIG
SHIFT IN THE PATTERNS.
SOME OF THIS MOISTURE IS GOING
TO MOVE ACROSS THE COUNTRY NEXT
WEEK.
WE MIGHT GET
>> ALL THAT WEATHER WAS BROUGHT
TO YOU BY FOLGERS.
MORE WEATHER IN THE NEXT HALF
HOUR.
>> SAM, THANK YOU.
COMING UP, HE'S THE STAR OF THE
HUNGRY GAMES.
ENGAGED TO THE MILEY CYRUS.
LIAM HEMSWORTH.
>>> ALSO AHEAD -- OUR VERY
FAVORITE PLAY OF THE WHOLE YEAR
A SPECIAL GUEST JOINING US TO
HELP BRING IT TO US.
HER NAME MIGHT RHYME WITH
HOBBIT.
>> WOW.
you can save the
things you love,
bring them all together,
And be inspired like
never before.
Scrapbooking. Create
yours with Nook HD -
and even bigger with HD+.
Find yours at Barnes & Noble.
GO TO WALGREENS.COM.
JUST UPLOAD YOUR PHOTO,
CREATE ANY NUMBER OF GIFTS
AND PICK THEM UP
THE SAME DAY.
RIGHT HERE.
AT THE CORNER
OF HAPPY AND HEALTHY.
she doesn't
Even though our really get us.
And she'll never know
who we are, or what...
No way,
Madden Girls??
Nike!
Who's your mommy now?
Famous brands. Famously easy.
Famous Footwear.
Victory is Yours.
MY NAME IS TAHO
AND I'M A FISH GUY.
IT'S A LABOR OF LOVE. IT'S A LOT
OF LABOR AND IT'S A LOT OF LOVE.
I DON'T NEED TO GO TO THE GYM.
MY JOB IS MY WORKOUT.
YOU'RE SHOVELING ICE
ALL DAY LONG.
IT'S ROUGH ON THE BACK.
IT'S ROUGH ON THE SHOULDERS.
I GET MUSCLE ACHES ALL OVER.
ADVIL® IS GREAT.
PAIN AND SORENESS
IS JUST OUT OF THE PICTURE.
[ Male Announcer ]
MAKE THE SWITCH.
TAKE ACTION. TAKE ADVIL®.
AND FOR SINUS CONGESTION,
NOW YOU CAN GET ADVIL® COMBINED
WITH A PROVEN DECONGESTANT.
BREATHE EASIER WITH ADVIL®
CONGESTION RELIEF.
♪ Target REDcard...
♪ Save 5% and get...
♪ free shipping!
♪ It's On. Hit the sale.
♪ Hallelujah.
Grab Your REDcard. ♪
♪ Hallelujah!
>>> BACK, NOW, AT 7:42, WITH THE
VIDEO OF A RISING, YOUNG FILM
STAR REPORTEDLY CAUGHT ON TAPE,
IN AN APPARENT STREET BRAWL IN
PHILADELPHIA.
"HUNGER GAMES" STAR, LIAM
HEMSWORTH, ENGAGED TO MILEY
CYRUS.
THE HOLLYWOOD HUNK, NOW IN HOT
WATER.
LINSEY DAVIS HAS THE STORY.
>> THEY WANT A GOOD SHOW.
THAT'S ALL THEY WANT.
>> Reporter: LIAM HEMSWORTH MAY
BE A VERSATILE ACTOR.
BUT THIS IS ONE ROLE WE HAVEN'T
SEEN HIM PLAY BEFORE.
WATCH AS THE MAN TMZ SAYS IS
HEMSWORTH SLUGS THIS GUY RIGHT
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE STREET,
USING SOME OF THE MUSCLE THE
STAR OF "THE HUNGER GAMES" MAY
ADDED WHILE PREPARING FOR HIS
ROLL IN "EXPENDABLES 2."
SOMETHING HE DISCUSSED ON "GOOD
MORNING AMERICA."
>> I LIFTED A LOT OF HEAVY
STUFF.
>> Reporter: THE ALTERCATION
BROKE OUT EARLY SUNDAY MORNING
IN, WHERE ELSE?
PHILADELPHIA.
THE CITY OF BROTHERLY LOVE.
ACCORDING TO TMZ, HEMSWORTH HAD
JUST LEFT A BAR, WHEN HE
CONFRONTED THIS MAN WHO HE
THOUGHT HAD THROWN A ROCK AT HIM
AND HIS FRIEND.
>> HIS BAD BOY IMAGE MAY BE
APPEALING TO SOME FANS.
PEOPLE IN THE CITY DON'T LIKE TO
SEE THIS TYPE OF THING.
>> Reporter: THE VICTIM CAN BE
SEEN CLINGING TO HIS ATTACKER'S
LEG, WHILE HE TAKES A BEATING
THAT ONLY STOPS WHEN A POLICE
CAR ARRIVES.
>> ACTUALLY, HE DID.
>> Reporter: WE'VE SEEN A
GLIMPSE OF HEMSWORTH'S BAD BOY
SIDE BEFORE.
BACK IN 2009, HE AND HIS BIG
BROTHER, CHRIS, REPORTEDLY GOT
INTO A FULL-ON FISTFIGHT WITH
ANOTHER MAN AFTER AN EVENT IN
HLTD.
HOLLYWOOD.
THAT WAS AROUND THE TIME HE
STARTED DATING HIS NOW-FIANCEE
MILEY CYRUS, WITH BOLD CARE CUTS
AND TATTOOS, HAS GAINED A
REBELLIOUS REPUTATION RECENTLY.
AS FAR AS HEMSWORTH'S SEEMINGLY
SPONTANEOUS EVENT, WITNESSES SAY
THEY NEVER SAW THE VICTIM THROW
THE ROCK THAT ALLEGEDLY STARTED
IT ALL.
FOR "GOOD MORNING AMERICA,"
LINSEY DAVIS, ABC NEWS,
NEW YORK.
>>> WE'RE REALLY EXCITED ABOUT
WHAT IS COMING UP NEXT.
THE AMERICAN HERO, JUST BACK
FROM THE FRONT LINES, IS ABOUT
TO GET THE SURPRISE OF HIS LIFE.
WE'VE FLOWN IN HIS FAMILY FOR AN
UNPRECEDENTED LIVE REUNION.
THEY CAN'T WAIT TO SEE HIM.
AND HE HAS NO IDEA THEY'RE
THERE.
>>> ALSO, WELL, WE'VE GOT IT.
MY VERY, VERY, VERY FAVORITE
PLAY OF THE WHOLE YEAR.
AND JOINING US TO BRING IT TO
YOU, AS WE FREEZE IT, ROBIN
MAST
EWELRY DESIGN
FOR CENTURIES."
♪
THIS LEVIAN COLLECTION
IS AMAZING.
MAYBE IT'S TIME
TO START YOUR OWN.
[ Female Announcer ]
KAY JEWELERS PRESENTS
TODAY'S LEVIAN COLLECTION...
[ gasps ]
FEATURING EXCLUSIVE
LEVIAN CHOCOLATE DIAMONDS.
FROM THE LEVIAN FAMILY -
WHERE THE LATEST IN FASHION
MEETS FINE JEWELRY.
ONE MORE REASON KAY
IS THE NUMBER-ONE JEWELRY STORE
IN AMERICA.
IT'S...
A WORK OF ART?
♪ EVERY KISS BEGINS WITH KAY
NAH, I'M GOOD.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] EVERY TIME
YOU SAY NO TO A CIGARETTE,
YOU CELEBRATE A LITTLE WIN.
NICODERM CQ, THE PATCH
WITH TIME RELEASE
SMART CONTROL TECHNOLOGY.
QUIT ONE DAY AT A TIME
WITH NICODERM CQ.
GO TO WALGREENS.COM.
JUST UPLOAD YOUR PHOTO,
CREATE ANY NUMBER OF GIFTS
AND PICK THEM UP
THE SAME DAY.
RIGHT HERE.
AT THE CORNER
OF HAPPY AND HEALTHY.
TRY OUR NEW
SOUTHWESTERN MAC AND CHEESE
WITH GRILLED CHICKEN,
SERVED WITH SOUP OR SALAD.
CHILI'S LUNCH COMBOS.
STARTING AT 6 BUCKS.
MORE LIFE HAPPENS HERE.
>>> RIGHT THEN, HERE'S "THE PLAY
OF THE DAY."
>> WE'VE ACTUALLY BEEN COUNTING
THE PLAYS OF THE YEAR.
BUT THEY ARE ALL GOING TO BE
TRUMPED.
EVEN TODAY'S VERY BEST ONE OF
ALL, BY THE GUEST WE BRING IN
RIGHT NOW TO BRING IT TO YOU
BECAUSE, LET'S BE HONEST, IT IS
CHOSEN FOR HER.
ROBIN ROBERTS.
>> GOOD MORNING, AMERICA.
GOOD MORNING, ALL.
I KNEW, JOSH, WHEN YOU ANNOUNCED
THE PLAYS OF THE YEAR, THAT THIS
WOULD BE ON THE LIST FOR FRIDAY.
HAPPY FRIDAY.
COME ON.
ROLL TAPE.
>> HERE WE GO.
ACTUALLY, THERE'S 1 AND 1A.
WE'RE GOING INTO THE TANK.
REMEMBER THIS GUY GETTING A HEAD
START.
>> ONE.
TWO.
>> THREE.
>> FOUR.
>> IT HURTS SO GOOD.
>> ALL RIGHT, ROBIN.
I WANT YOU TO SET THIS UP
BECAUSE THIS MAY HAVE BEEN THE
GREATEST PIECE OF VIDEOTAPE
WE'LL EVER SEE.
>> MAY I?
MAY I, JOSH?
>> YES.
ROBIN ROBERTS IS BACK.
>> I DON'T WANT YOU TO FREEZE
IT.
THIS IS THE ONE THAT WE ALL WENT
CRAZY FOR.
LOOK AT THESE KIDS.
HI-YA.
AND GET HIM.
>> I FORGOT ABOUT THOSE GUYS.
>> THEY NEVER TOUCH EACH OTHER,
WHICH IS GREAT.
>> THEY HAVE THAT PROTECTIVE
GEAR ON.
>> THEY WERE NEVER IN ANY
DANGER.
>> NO.
I WILL SAY, THE DEGREE OF
DIFFICULTY IN THOSE HIGH HEEL,
YOU WIN EVERY TIME.
TERRIFIC.
ROBIN, HOW ARE YOU DOING?
LET'S BE HONEST.
YOU'RE THE SPECIAL GUEST OF THE
YEAR.
>> OH, COME ON.
IT'S ALL ABOUT "THE PLAY OF THE
DAY."
HAVE YOU BEEN DIPPING IN THE
EGGNOG THIS WEEK, BY THE WAY?
JUST WATCHING AND THINKING,
FINDING APPLE JACKS -- ALL IS
WELL.
HAPPY FRIDAY TO ALL.
HAPPY PLAY OF THE YEAR.
AND EVERYTHING IS FANTASTIC.
>> IT WAS DESPITE THE APPLE
JACKS, I DO BELIEVE.
AND SO, ROBIN, MAYBE YOU JOIN US
NEXT WEEK BECAUSE WE ARE NOW
GOING TO HAVE EVERYBODY VOTING
IN AMERICA FOR THEIR FAVORITE
PLAYS OF THE YEAR.
I KNOW SOMEBODY WHO KNOWS
SOMEBODY.
MAYBE WE'LL GET ROBIN BACK FOR
THAT ONE, AS WELL.
UNTIL THEN, MY FRIEND, GREAT SO
SEE YOU.
>> LOVE YOU.
IT'S TIME TO GET REAL ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENS IN THE BATHROOM.
AND START TALKING ABOUT
WHAT YOU REALLY WANT
FROM YOUR TOILET PAPER.
IT'S TIME TO TALK ABOUT CLEAN.
FEELING CLEAN IS SO IMPORTANT.
I USE QUILTED NORTHERN.
QUILTED NORTHERN SOFT AND STRONG
IS STRONGER THAN THE
LEADING VALUE BRAND,
FOR A CONFIDENT CLEAN.
He is a good little monkey
and always very curious.
One day George got an important
letter...
He's built a rocket ship to
travel into space.
It's just the right size for a
clever monkey.
Do you want to go into space,
George?
You will have to be very brave.
Hi, Grandma!
Oh hi,. my little monkey!
Here.
Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
Everyone got on and they were
off to the launching site.
Google, how far is Earth to the
Moon?
Moon is 238,900 miles...
The great moment had come...
...5...4...3...2...1
DAISY IS 100% PURE
WITH NOTHING ELSE ADDED.
MEALS ARE SIMPLY BETTER
WITH A DOLLOP OF DAISY.
♪
♪ DO A DOLLOP,
DO, DO A DOLLOP OF DAISY ♪
♪
MAYBMAYBE YOU CAN'T.RE;
WHEN YOU HAVE MIGRAINES
WITH FIFTEEN OR MORE
HEADACHE DAYS A MONTH,
YOU MISS OUT ON YOUR LIFE.
YOU MAY HAVE CHRONIC MIGRAINE.
GO TO MYCHRONICMIGRAINE.COM
TO FIND A HEADACHE
SPECIALIST.
AND DON'T LIVE
A MAYBE LIFE.
Music: "Make Someone Happy"
♪It's so important to make
someone happy.♪
♪Make just one heart to heart
you - you sing to♪
♪One smile that cheers you
♪One face that lights when it
nears you.♪
♪And you will be happy too.
>>> PG&E IS RUSHING TO INSPECT
MORE THAN 1600 PIECES OF UNDER
GROUND ELECTRICAL EQUIPMENT FOR
POSSIBLE SAFETY HAZARDS.
THIS COMES AFTER THE UTILITY
SAYS IT HAS FIRED OR SUSPENDED
EMPLOYEES WHO HAVE CLAIMED TO
INSPECTED EQUIPMENT THEY HAD
NOT.
>> WE'LL START WITH LIVE
DOPPLER.
YOU CAN SEE RADAR RETURNS, MOST
OF IT IS NOT MAKING IT TO THE
GROUND UNTIL YOU GET OUT TO ON
THE COAST.
30s AND 40s IS WHAT WE HAVE
RIGHT NOW.
STRAY HOURS SHOWERS AND POSSIBLY
40s AND 50s, BETTER CHANCES OF
RAIN SATURDAY AND SUNDAY.
>> METERING LIGHTS ON, TRAFFIC
BACKED UP PAST THE OVERCROSSING.
SLOW THROUGH HAYWARD AND
ANDROTTI OFF-RAMP IS STALLED
WITH A BIG
♪ YOU CAME HERE WITH SOMEONE
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>>> THE CROWD IS EVEN BIGGER.
OUT BY THE POINSETTIAS.
AND RIGHT INSIDE HERE, WE HAVE
DEEJAY.
A DANCING SNOWMAN.
>> WE DO.
>> I'D LIKE TO SHOW THE DANCING
SNOWMAN.
>> THERE WE GO.
>> AWESOME.
>> HAPPY FRIDAY.
HOW GREAT WAS IT TO HEAR ROBIN
CALL IN ON "THE PLAY OF THE
DAY"?
THAT WAS FANTASTIC.
AND THE DANCING SNOWMAN, AS
WELL.
>> FROSTY HAS MOVES.
>> yES, HE DOES.
>> I REMEMBER WHEN WE DID THAT
"PLAY OF THE DAY" THE FIRST
TIME.
ROBIN'S FACE WAS -- SHE WAS LIKE
A 6-YEAR-OLD GIRL ON CHRISTMAS
ALL OF A SUDDEN.
>> WELCOME TO AMY ROBACH.
THANK YOU FOR GIVING ME THE
PRONUNCIATION LESSON YESTERDAY.
SAM HAS TO WORK ON IT.
>>> WE ARE GOING TO LOOK AT
HOLIDAYS WITH MOCKTAILS.
NONALCOHOLIC HOLIDAY DRINKS.
SERVING UP WHAT HE CALLS HIS
CHRISTMAS TREE.
>> THANK YOU, SIR.
>> SEASONS GREETINGS.
>> WHAT DO WE HAVE HERE?
>> THIS IS JUNIPER SODA, WITH
CRANBERRY JUICE.
>> THERE'S A COMPANY OUT OF
SEATTLE.
JUNIPER SODA,
NOT A LOT OF SUGAR.
A LITTLE BIT OF CRANBERRIES.
>> IS THIS ROSEMARY?
>> THAT IS ROSEMARY.
>> THANK YOU.
HAPPY FRIDAY, Y'ALL.
>> THAT'S GOOD.
>> IT IS GOOD.
>> HEY, BLAISE, MOCKTAILS.
REALLY NICE.
>> MOCKTAILS.
>>> ALSO, REMEMBER THAT SNEAKY
SNOWMAN WE SHOWED DURING "PLAY
OF THE DAY" A WHILE BACK.
NOW, DANCING FOR US HERE IN OUR
STUDIO.
TURNS OUT WE DO HAVE A "GMA"
SNOWMAN, WHO WAS ACTUALLY
WAITING IN THE LOADING DOCKS.
AND ENDED UP SURPRISING A COUPLE
FOLKS.
>> BOO.
>> WHO IS THAT?
>> WHO COULD HAVE THAT BEEN?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
>> THAT MIGHT HAVE BEEN AMY,
RIGHT?
>> YEAH.
>> POOR THING.
>> I HAD MY COFFEE.
>> IT GETS BETTER.
IT ACTUALLY GETS BETTER.
>> WHEN YOU'RE THE ONE THAT'S
NOT ON THE RECEIVING END.
PUNK'd LIKE THAT.
>>> WE ALSO HAVE BRAND-NEW
DETAILS FROM "DANCING WITH THE
STARS" HOST BROOKE BURKE
CHARVET.
WHAT SHE'S REVEALING ABOUT HER
HEALTH.
IT'S GOOD NEWS.
>>> AND IT IS AN EMOTIONAL, BY
THE WAY, UNPRECEDENTED LIVE
"GMA" EVENT.
THE SOLDIER WHO IS ON THE SCREEN
RIGHT NOW, WHO CAN'T HEAR US,
THINKS HE'S ACTUALLY THERE TO
SAY HELLO TO THE TROOPS WHO ARE
IN AFGHANISTAN.
HE JUST GOT BACK FROM THE FRONT
LINES.
BUT WE FLEW HIS FAMILY IN TO THE
BE REUNITED WITH HIM.
AND THEY CAN HEAR US.
NOBODY KNOWS WHAT'S GOING ON.
EVERYBODY KNOWS THAT THEY'RE
THERE FOR SOMETHING.
BUT THEY HAVE NO IDEA WHAT'S
HAPPENING.
JUST A FEW MINUTES AWAY.
>>> FIRST, WE HAVE TO GET THE
NEWS FROM JOSH.
>>> GOOD MORNING TO ALL OF YOU,
YOU WERE JUST WATCHING AN
EARLIER TAPED PORTION OF "GOOD
MORNING AMERICA."
BUT WE HAVE BREAKING NEWS NOW
FOR YOU ON TO WEST COAST.
I'M JOSH ELLIOTT ALONGSIDE AMY
ROBACH.
YOU'RE SEEING HERE A MAP OF
CONNECTICUT.
A SCHOOL SHOOTING AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
TWO HOURS TO THE NORTH AND EAST
OF NEW YORK CITY.
THE IMAGES YOU SEE HERE,
CHILDREN BEING FROM SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE DISTRICT'S LARGEST SCHOOL.
ONE SHOOTER IS DEAD AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY.
THE SCHOOL NOW CLEARED OF
SHOOTERS.
NEWTOWN POLICE SAY THERE'S AT
LEAST ONE OTHER PERSON SHOT.
POLICE TELLING ABC NEWS THAT
THEY'RE STILL TREATING THIS AS
AN ACTIVE SHOOTER SITUATION.
STATE EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT
OFFICIALS CONFIRMING THAT
AMBULANCES AND OTHER UNITS ARE
EN ROUTE AND STAGING NEAR THE
SCHOOL.
AGAIN, THESE ARE PICTURES FROM
THE PARK ING LOT OF THE SCHOOL.
POLICE ALSO BELIEVE THEY MAY
HAVE LOCATED THE SUSPECT'S CAR,
AGAIN, AS WE JUST ARE GETTING
INFORMATION HERE, AND AGAIN,
IT'S SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, ABOUT 15 MILES FROM
DANBURY, ANOTHER MAJOR CITY IN
CONNECTICUT.
TWO HOURS NORTH AND EAST OFFING
NEW YORK CITY.
>> OBVIOUSLY, OF INCREDIBLE
CONCERN IS THE EXTENT OF THE
INJURIES THAT MAY HAVE OCCURRED
THERE AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
WE DO KNOW ACCORDING TO THE
NEWTOWN BEE ON THE SCENE THAT
THERE WAS ONE CHILD CARRIED FROM
THE SCHOOL BY POLICE, SERIOUSLY
WOUNDED.
ANOTHER INJURIES HAVE BEEN
REPORTED WE KNOW THAT THESE
EMERGENCY PERSONNEL GATHERED
THEIR ENMASS, THE EXTENTS OF THE
INJURIES UNCLEAR.
ACCORDING TO THE WEBSITE OF
NEWTOWN SCHOOL, AFTERNOON BUSES
AND KINDERGARTEN IS CANCELED.
THE SUPERINTENDENT ISSUING THIS
STATEMENT, THE DISTRICT IS
TAKING PREVENTIVE MEASURES BY
PUTTING ALL SCHOOLS IN LOCKDOWN
UNTIL WE ASSURE SAFETY OF ALL
STUDENTS AND STAFF.
>> WE CAN TAKE YOU THROUGH A
TIME LINE AS IT'S COME
AVAILABLE.
THIS ACCORDING TO THE
CURRENT.COM.
WEBSITE OF THE HARTFORD COURANT.
THE SHOOTER WAS IN FACT IN THE
MAIN OFFICE OF THE SCHOOL,
AGAIN, UNCONFIRMED REPORTS OF
TWO SHOOTERS, WE DO OF COURSE,
WE CAN CONFIRM ONE SHOOTER HAS
BEEN KILLED.
ANOTHER PERHAPSES AT LARGE.
WE DON'T HAVE THAT CONFIRMED.
AND AGAIN, AS OF 10:30 EASTERN,
STUDENTS WERE STILL BEING LED AS
YOU SEE THE STUDENTS HERE, LED
FROM THE SCHOOL, BY THEIR
TEACHERS.
AGAIN, WE CAN TELL YOU NOW, IT'S
AN ACTIVE SHOOTER SCENE, THOUGH
THE SCHOOL ITSELF HAS BEEN
CLEARED.
WE DID RECEIVE REPORTS AS WELL
THAT THE FBI, S.W.A.T. TEAM WAS
ON SCENE.
WE WANT TO BRING IN A FORMER IF
FBI SPECIAL AGENT, BRAD GARRETT
JOINING US BY PHONE.
REPORTS OF S.W.A.T. AND FBI HAVE
RESPONDED ALONG WITH STATE
POLICE AS THEY LOCKED DOWN THAT
SCHOOL, WHAT IS THE FIRST THING
THEY'RE LOOKING TO DO.
>> TO ENSURE THEY'VE GOT THE
SITUATION CONTAINED, JOSH.
THE PROBLEM IS, YOU STILL DON'T
KNOW, THEY DON'T KNOW PERHAPS
HOW MANY SHOOTERS THEY MIGHT
HAVE, HAVE THEY DONE ANYTHING
ELSE TO THE SCHOOL, THINK ABOUT
HARRIS AND KLEBOLD AT COLUNBINE.
THE SECOND IS, DO YOU HAVE ANY
TEACHERS, CHILDREN INJURED TO
GET OUT OF THE BUILDING TO SAVE
THEIR LIVES.
>> ONE SHOOTER IS CONFIRMED
DEAD.
THEY DO BELIEVE THAT THERE MAY
HAVE BEEN A SECOND SHOOTER.
THEY HAVE CLEARED THE SCHOOL,
I'M IMAGINING THAT SEARCH MAY GO
WELL BEYOND THE SCHOOL, LOOKING
FOR A PERSON POTENTIALLY AT
LARGE?
>> DEFINITELY.
IF IN FACT THERE'S A SECOND
SHOOTER THE PROBLEM IN THESE
CASES IS THAT PEOPLE, SOMETIMES
SEE THINGS THAT AREN'T EXACTLY
ACCURATE.
THERE MIGHT ONLY BE ONE SHOOTER,
BECAUSE PEOPLE CAUGHT IT A
CERTAIN WAY THINK THERE MAY BE
TWO.
>> THE DISTRICT HAS ASKED
PARENTS NOT TO FLOOD DISTRICT
PHONES WITH CALLS, EVERY PARENT
WANT TO KNOW THAT THEIR CHILDREN
ARE SAFE, I'M CERTAIN MANY
PARENTS NOW MAKING THEIR WAY TO
THE SCHOOL, WHAT WOULD TELL
PARENTS RIGHT NOW AS THEY'RE
MAKING THEIR WAY TO AN ACTIVE
CRIME SCENE?
>> TYPICALLY WHAT THE POLICE DO
IS SET UP A CHECK POINT AT THE
SCHOOL WHERE THEY CAN GO IN AND
CHECK IN WITH AN OFFICER,
BECAUSE THE PROBLEM IS, FIGURING
OUT WHERE THE CHILDREN ARE, WHO
HAS BEEN ACCOUNTED FOR AND WHO
HAS NOT IS GOING TO TAKE A
WHILE.
THE REAL KEY IS, KEEPING PARENTS
INFORMED.
KEEPING THEM OFF THE PHONE AND
KEEPING THEM AWAY FROM THE
SCHOOL.
>> WE HAVE A MOTHER WHO ATTEND
THE SCHOOL.
MYRA, YOU HAVE YOUR CHILDREN
WITH YOU AND THEY'RE SAFE?
>> HELLO.
>> THIS IS AMY, TRYING TO FIND
OUT WHAT YOU HAVE BEEN ABLE TO
OBTAIN.
I KNOW YOUR CHILDREN ARE SAFE
WITH YOU NOW, WHAT HAVE YOU
SEEN?
>> MY CHILDREN ARE AT THEIR
SCHOOL.
THEY DON'T GO TO THESE SANDY
HOOK SCHOOLS.
>> WHAT HAVE YOU BEEN ABLE TO
FIND OUT?
>> WE'RE FINDING OUT THAT
PARENTS HAVE BEEN ABLE TO GET
THEIR KIDS.
ONE OF MY FRIEND WHO I'M TRYING
TO CONTACT RIGHT NOW, HAVE A
CHILD.
MY CHILDREN GO TO A DIFFERENT
SCHOOL, I'M AT THE SANDY HOOK
DELI.
ALL WE'RE SEEING IS AMBULANCES,
STATE TROOPERS.
PARENTS RUNNING TO GET TO THE
SCHOOL.
SOME PARENTS HAVE THEIR KIDS.
SOME DON'T.
>> WE CAN ONLY IMAGINE THE CHAOS
AND THE FEAR THERE WITH THOSE
PARENTS DESPERATELY TRYING TO
LOCATE THEIR CHILDREN.
>> AGAIN, THE NEWS A SHOOTING AT
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AT NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WE'LL RETURN, THOUGH, TO "GOOD
MORNING AMERICA," ON THE WEST
COAST.
AND FOR A LOOK AT THE NATION'S
WEATHER.
HERE'S SAM CHAMPION.
>>> GOOD MORNING, HOW ARE YOU?
NICE TO SEE YOU.
>> GOOD MORNING, YOU GUYS.
WHERE ARE YOU ALL FROM?
>> SOUTH CAROLINA.
>> YOU GOT TO GET ON TV THIS
MORNING.
>> ALL RIGHT, LET'S GET TO THE
BOARDS.
HERE'S A COUPLE OF THINGS THAT
WE WANT TO SHARE WITH YOU.
A BIG PATTERN CHANGE COMING INTO
THE COUNTRY THIS WEEKEND.
WE'LL TRY TO GET SOME COLD AIR
MIXED IN THEM WITH AS WELL.
SO, WE'LL BE LOOKING FOR THAT.
THAT STARTS THIS WEEKEND INTO
NEXT WEEK.
NOW, THE WEEKEND HAS GOTTEN AN
AWFUL LOT OF WARM AIR W THAT,
WE'LL SEE THIS FALLING IN THE
FORM OF STORMS.
STRONG STORMS ARE POSSIBLE ON
THAT LINE.
BUT NEXT WEEK, WE'LL START TO
GET SOME COLD AIR BLENDING IN.
QUICK LOOK AT
>>> THAT'S NOT ENOUGH GMA.
HERE'S WHAT EYE AES HEAD
"DANCING WITH THE STARS" BROOKE
BURKE-CHARVET.
THE LATEST ON HER MEDICAL
BATTLE.
>>> AND UNPRECEDENTED "GOOD
MORNING AMERICA" LIVE EVENT.
THIS SOLDIER DAD IS ABOUT TO GET
THE SURPRISE OF HIS LIFE WHEN WE
REUNITE HIM WITH HIS FAMILY
RIGHT HERE ON "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA."
>>> THE FAVORITE PICK FOR THE
HOLIDAY SEASON.
A LITTLE HOLIDAY BLING.
STAY WITH US.
ALL THAT WITH D.J. SUGAR RAY,
LIVE RIGHT HERE ON "GMA."
STAY WITH US.
BURST ADULT MULTIVITAMINS...
A DELICIOUS NEW WAY TO GET
ESSENTIAL VITAMINS YOU NEED.
JUST BITE
INTO THE TASTY SHELL...
TO A CHEWY VITAMIN CORE
FOR A UNIQUE
MULTIVITAMIN SENSATION!
NEW CENTRUM FLAVOR BURST.
SO ALL OF YOU DO.
YES, FOR SURE.
NOW WHAT'S BETTER?
BEING ABLE TO SHOOT TWO LASERS
OUT OF BOTH OF YOUR EYES
AT THE SAME TIME
OR JUST ONE LASER
OUT OF ONE EYE?
[ all kids ] TWO!
[ Moderator ] OKAY, WHY?
IF IT'S JUST ONE BEAM -- OKAY,
IT DOES A LITTLE BIT OF DAMAGE.
TWO BEAMS -- IT WILL
MAKE SOMETHING EXPLODE!
AND THAT'S MORE FUN?
YEAH!
AND IT'S MORE POWERFUL
YOU'RE SAYING?
YEAH!
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S NOT COMPLICATED.
DOING TWO THINGS AT ONCE
IS BETTER.
AND ONLY AT&T'S NETWORK
LETS YOU TALK AND SURF
ON YOUR IPHONE 5.
♪
LIVING WITH MODERATE TO
SEMEANS LIVING WITH PAIN.IS
IT COULD ALSO MEAN
LIVING WITH JOINT DAMAGE.
HELP RELIEVE THE PAIN
AND STOP THE DAMAGE
WITH HUMIRA, ADALIMUMAB.
FOR MANY ADULTS WITH
MODERATE TO SEVERE RA,
HUMIRA IS CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO HELP RELIEVE PAIN
AND STOP JOINT DAMAGE.
SO YOU CAN TREAT MORE
THAN JUST THE PAIN.
HUMIRA CAN LOWER YOUR
ABILITY TO FIGHT INFECTIONS,
INCLUDING TUBERCULOSIS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL EVENTS,
SUCH AS INFECTIONS, LYMPHOMA,
OR OTHER TYPES OF
CANCER, HAVE HAPPENED.
BLOOD, LIVER AND
NERVOUS SYSTEM PROBLEMS,
SERIOUS ALLERGIC REACTIONS,
AND NEW OR WORSENING HEART
FAILURE HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING HUMIRA, YOUR
DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU FOR TB.
ASK YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU LIVE
IN OR HAVE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL
INFECTIONS ARE COMMON.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU
HAVE HAD TB, HEPATITIS B,
ARE PRONE TO INFECTIONS
OR HAVE SYMPTOMS SUCH AS
FEVER, FATIGUE, COUGH, OR SORES.
YOU SHOULD NOT START HUMIRA IF
YOU HAVE ANY KIND OF INFECTION.
ASK YOUR RHEUMATOLOGIST ABOUT
HUMIRA, TO HELP RELIEVE PAIN
AND STOP FURTHER JOINT DAMAGE
BEFORE THEY STOP YOU.
♪ I WOKE UP TO A FEELING
♪ EVERY LITTLE THING
HAS MEANING ♪
♪ I WOKE UP TO A LIGHT BULB ON
♪ EVERY LITTLE THING
IS POSSIBLE NOW ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
WE'VE ADDED A TOUCH OF
PHILADELPHIA CREAM CHEESE
TO OUR KRAFT NATURAL CHEESE
TO MAKE IT CREAMIER
SO WHATEVER YOU MAKE
ISN'T JUST GOOD, IT'S AMAZING.
♪ ...IS AMAZING
WITH THE LOVE THAT I FOUND ♪
♪
THANKS TO NEW JIF CHOCOLATE
FLAVORED HAZELNUT SPREAD.
♪
NOW ANYTIME OF THE DAY
CAN BE DELICIOUS TIME.
♪
CHOOSY MOMS CHOOSE JIF.
TO THE BEST VACATION
SP(ALL) THE GULF!
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHICH OF
OUR GREAT STATES FOLKS VISIT.
MISSISSIPPI,
ALABAMA,
LOUISIANA
OR FLORIDA,
THEY'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
SHAUL, YOUR ALABAMA
HOSPITALITY IS INCREDIBLE.
THANKS, KAREN.
LOVE YOUR MISSISSIPPI OUTDOORS.
I VOTE FOR YOUR
FLORIDA BEACHES, DAWN.
BILL, THIS LOUISIANA
SEAFOOD IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR ON THE GULF,
WE'VE DECIDED TO PUT
ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
NOW IS THE PERFECT TIME TO
VISIT ANYONE OF OUR STATES.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE, GO FISHING
OR JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
WE'VE GOT COASTLINE TO EXPLORE
AND WILDLIFE TO PHOTOGRAPH.
AND THERE'S WORLD CLASS DINING
WITH OUR WORLD FAMOUS SEAFOOD.
SO FOR A GREAT VACATION
THIS YEAR, COME TO THE GULF.
ITS ALL FABULOUS BUT
I GIVE FLORIDA THE EDGE.
RIGHT AFTER MISSISSIPPI.
YOU MEAN ALABAMA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
THIS INVITATION IS
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP
AND ALL OF US WHO
CALL THE GULF HOME.
♪
[Spider-Man]
WE GOT THIS.
♪
[Mom]
THIS HERO STUFF IS EASY!
>>> COMING UP -- "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA'S" COUNTDOWN TO
CHRISTMAS GIFTS ON A BUDGET.
PRESENTED BY TARGET.
DREAM BIG, SAVE BIGGER.
>>> NOW, THE ANSWER TO OUR POP
QUIZ.
WE ASKED YOU, WHO TOPS THE LIST
FOR MOST POLITE CELEBRITY OF THE
YEAR?
WELL, THE ANSWER IS MISS TAYLOR
SWIFT.
NUMBER THREE WAS OUR VERY OWN
ROBIN ROBERTS.
NOT SURPRISING.
>> WHO WAS NUMBER TWO?
>> I FORGET.
FOLLOW-UP-FREE.
COME ON, NOW, GEORGE.
>>> WE HAVE SOME GOOD NEWS FOR
"DANCING WITH THE STARS" HOST
BROOKE BURKE-CHARVET.
WE'VE BEEN FOLLOWING HER BATTLE
WITH THYROID CANCER.
NOW, A WEEK AFTER HER SURGERY,
SHE REVEALED SHE IS CANCER-FREE
AND RECOVERING.
ABC'S PAULA FARIS HAS HER STORY.
>> Reporter: IT'S THE PERFECT
SCORE SHE'S BEEN WAITING FOR.
"DANCING WITH THE STARS" CO-HOST
BROOKE BURKE-CHARVET REVEALING
THAT SHE HAS A CLEAN BILL OF
HEALTH AFTER HER RECENT BATTLE
WITH THYROID CANCER.
SHARING THE GOOD NEWS ON HER
BLOG WEDNESDAY, WRITING THE
THYROID CANCER HAS BEEN REMOVED
FROM MY BODY.
AND ALL OF MY LYMPH NODES ARE
CLEAR.
SO, I'M HOPING THIS IS THE END
OF THE STORY.
THE 41-YEAR-OLD MOTHER OF FOUR
UNDERWENT A THYROIDECTOMY, JUST
NINE DAYS AGO.
TO REMOVE A CANCEROUS NODULE ON
HER THYROID.
BUT NOW, SHE'S ON THE FAST TRACK
TO RECOVERY.
EVERY DAY I'M FEELING BETTER.
AND I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO
GETTING BACK TO MY USUAL
ROUTINE, BUT WITH A BIT OF A
DIFFERENT OUTLOOK, WITH A
NEWFOUND RESPECT FOR LIFE.
>> WHEN IT COMES TO THIS
PARTICULAR CANCER, WE REALLY DO
SEEM TO HAVE A VERY GOOD CONTROL
RATE.
YOUR CHANCE OF SURVIVING A
THYROID CANCER IS EXTREMELY
HIGH.
>> Reporter: BURKE CHARVET'S
FAMOUS FOR HER COMMITMENT TO
HEALTH AND FITNESS, REVEALED HER
SHOCKING DIAGNOSIS EARLY LAST
MONTH, AFTER A ROUTINE TRIP TO
THE DOCTOR.
>> I NEED TO HAVE THYROID
SURGERY AND HAVE A
THYROIDECTOMY, WHICH MEANS I'M
GOING TO HAVE A NICE, BIG SCAR
RIGHT HERE ACROSS MY NECK.
>> Reporter: DOCUMENTING EVERY
STEP OF HER BATTLE ON SOCIAL
MEDIA.
FROM HOW SHE TOLD HER CHILDREN
SHE HAD CANCER, TO THIS PHOTO OF
THE SURGICAL SCAR ON HER NECK.
EAGER TO SPREAD HOPE TO OTHER
WOMEN.
>> I'VE NEVER FELT BETTER.
>> Reporter: BUT EVEN CANCER
CAN'T SLOW DOWN THIS BUSY MOM.
THE FITNESS BUFF ANNOUNCED THE
RELEASE OF A NEW LINE OF WORKOUT
DVDs ON MONDAY.
ADDING TO HER WILDLY SUCCESSFUL
SERIES.
>> CRUNCH 'EM.
>> Reporter: WHILE SHE MAY BE
FORCED TO HANG UP HER SNEAKERS
FOR ANOTHER WEEK OR TWO, BURKE
CHARVET IS AT HOME RELAXING,
PAINTING AND TAKING FRENCH
LESSONS.
SAYING I'VE TAKEN THE REST OF
THE YEAR OFF TO CATCH UP WITH MY
FAMILY.
AND NOW, WE'RE JUST CELEBRATING
LIFE.
>> THIS IS AMAZING.
>> Reporter: FOR "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA," PAULA FARIS, ABC NEWS,
NEW YORK.
>> THAT'S GOOD NEWS.
SHE'S MAKING PROGRESS.
>>> AND NOW, WE HAVE A VERY
SPECIAL EVENT RIGHT HERE ON
"GMA."
A FAMILY REUNION FOR CAPTAIN
GERRY GARCIA.
HE'S JUST BACK FROM AFGHANISTAN.
IT TOOK ALL KINDS OF MANEUVERS
TO PULL OFF THIS SURPRISE.
THERE YOU SEE HIM.
THAT'S CAPTAIN GARCIA.
HE THINKS HE'S JOINING "GMA" TO
GIVE A HOLIDAY GREETING TO HIS
FELLOW TROOPS STILL ON THE FRONT
LINES.
HE HAS NO IDEA HE'S ABOUT TO SEE
HIS WIFE AND KIDS, RIGHT THERE,
RIGHT NEXT DOOR WITH CAM
MATHISON FOR THE FIRST TIME IN
ALMOST A YEAR.
CAM, HOW IS EVERYBODY DOING?
>> WE ARE BEYOND EXCITED HERE.
COME ON, GUYS.
WE'RE GOING THIS WAY.
BUT WE'RE DOING OUR BEST TO KEEP
IT QUIET, OBVIOUSLY, BECAUSE
CAPTAIN GARCIA IS LITERALLY,
COME ON WITH ME, RIGHT ON THE
OTHER SIDE OF THIS DOOR RIGHT
HERE.
SO, OBVIOUSLY, WE DON'T WANT TO
GIVE IT AWAY.
WE'VE BEEN PLANNING THIS FAR TOO
LONG.
BUT BEFORE WE GET TO THE BIG
MOMENT, THE BIG REVEAL, LET'S
TAKE A LOOK AT THE GARCIA FAMILY
HISTORY.
>> MY HUSBAND'S NAME IS GERARDO.
I'VE BEEN MARRIED TO HIM FOR TEN
YEARS.
WE MET IN THE MILITARY.
I CAUGHT HIS EYE.
AND HE CAUGHT MY EYE.
THE REST IS HISTORY.
HE'S A FUNNY GUY.
HE LIKES TO MAKE JOKES.
WE ARE ALWAYS PLAYING JOKES ON
EACH OTHER OR THE CHILDREN.
>> HE CALLS ME THE FUZZY MAN.
>> IS THAT SANTA?
I HAVE THREE KIDS.
MARK IS OUR OLDEST.
HE'S 10.
ALESSANDRA, SHE'S 6.
AND OUR BABY IS 3.
>> HI.
>> Reporter: BUT HER HUSBAND,
CAPTAIN GERARDO GARCIA IS ON HIS
FOURTH DEPLOYMENT IN
AFGHANISTAN, WHILE ANDREA HOLDS
DOWN THE FORT IN CALIFORNIA.
>> YOU LOVE WHAT YOU DO,
YOU LOVE YOUR HUSBAND SO MUCH,
YOU MAKE SACRIFICES.
>> Reporter: WHILE GERARDO
SERVES HIS COUNTRY, ANDREA IS
IN SCHOOL,
GETTING HER NURSING DEGREE.
>> I NEED TO BE A MODEL FOR
THEM, TOO.
THAT'S WHY IT WAS IMPORTANT FOR
ME TO GO TO SCHOOL, TO BETTER
MYSELF, SO THEY CAN SEE MOMMY
CAN MAKE A DIFFERENCE WHILE
THEIR DAD'S GONE.
>> Reporter: BUT RAISING THREE
KIDS, ESSENTIALLY AS A SINGLE
PARENT, CAN TAKE A TREMENDOUS
EMOTIONAL TOLL.
>> IT'S HARD.
THEY DON'T GET TO SEE THEIR DAD
IN THE MORNING.
TO SAY, HI, HOW WAS YOUR DAY?
OR GET THEIR DAD TO MAKE THEM
PANCAKES THEY USED TO MAKE ON
SUNDAYS.
THINGS THAT NORMAL PARENTS DO
FOR THEIR KIDS.
>> Reporter: BUT NOW, CHRISTMAS
IS COMING.
AND THAT MEANS CAPTAIN GERARDO
GARCIA IS COMING HOME FOR THE
HOLIDAYS.
BUT WITH A SPECIAL TWIST.
HE HAS NO IDEA HIS FAMILY IS
COMING TO THE BASE TODAY.
AN INCREDIBLE EARLY CHRISTMAS
SURPRISE.
>> I'M SO READY TO BE ABLE TO
HUG HIM AND KISS HIM AND LOVE ON
HIM.
AND JUST BE TOGETHER.
THE TOGETHERNESS IS WHAT I MISS
IS MOST.
>> HI, DADDY.
>> HI, DAD.
>> I MISS YOU, DADDY.
>> WE ARE ALL READY FOR IT, TOO,
RIGHT NOW.
CANNOT WAIT FOR THIS MOMENT.
SO, YOU GUYS, CAN YOU OPEN MY
MIC TO CAPTAIN GARCIA, PLEASE?
HEY, CAPTAIN GARCIA.
GEORGE STEPHANOPOULOS HERE.
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
>> YES, I CAN HEAR YOU.
>> I WANT TO THANK YOU FOR YOUR
SERVICE TO THIS COUNTRY.
FOUR TOURS IN AFGHANISTAN.
THAT'S A TREMENDOUS SACRIFICE I
KNOW YOU HAVE MADE.
AND I KNOW YOU'RE THERE NOW TO
SEND A HOLIDAY HOOHA TO ALL OF
YOUR FELLOW TROOPS IN IRAQ AND
AFGHANISTAN.
WE'LL DO THAT IN A SECOND.
BEFORE YOU DO THAT, CAN YOU JUST
TURN AROUND FOR A SECOND?
>> UM -- I'M SORRY --
>> CAN YOU JUST TURN AROUND?
>> TURN AROUND, YOU SAID?
>> YEAH.
CAN YOU TURN AROUND BEFORE WE DO
THE GREETING?
>> OH.
HI.
WHAT ARE YOU GUYS DOING TO ME?
WOW.
LOVE YOU.
>> SURPRISE.
>> THERE IS REAL SURPRISE.
OH, THAT IS SUCH A HAPPY MOMENT.
>> I'M CAMERON MATHISON FOR
"GOOD MORNING AMERICA."
I'M THE EYES AND EARS BEHIND THE
SCENES.
WE WANTED TO SURPRISE YOU.
I HEAR THAT YOU ARE NORMALLY THE
FAMILY'S PRACTICAL JOKER.
HOW DO YOU THINK ANDREA DID?
DID SHE SURPRISE YOU?
>> YEAH.
I'M SPEECHLESS.
I DON'T EVEN HAVE ANYTHING TO
SAY BECAUSE I'M TOTALLY CAUGHT
OFF GUARD HERE.
>> YOU DIDN'T WANT TO TURN
AROUND.
>> YEAH.
>> I KNOW GEORGE IN NEW YORK
WANTS TO CHECK IN WITH YOU, AS
WELL.
>> OH, WE LOVED SEEING THAT
MOMENT.
YOU WERE SO INTENT ON FOLLOWING
THE DIRECTIONS SO WELL.
YOU ALMOST MISSED THE SURPRISE
RIGHT THERE.
ANDREA, I WANT TO ASK YOU.
YOU HAD TO COOK UP SUCH AN
ELABORATE PLAN TO PULL OFF THIS
SURPRISE.
HOW DID YOU DO IT?
>> I HAD A LOT OF POSTING ON
FACEBOOK, ELABORATE POSTS ON
FACEBOOK.
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT I DID TO
TAKE OFF THIS PLAN.
AND LUCKILY, YOU KNOW, HE TRUSTS
ME SO MUCH, IT WAS VERY
BELIEVABLE.
>> NOT AFTER TODAY.
>> AND I LOVE SEEING THE SMILE
ON YOUR KIDS' FACES RIGHT NOW.
THEY'RE GOING TO GET THEIR
PANCAKES THIS WEEKEND, CAPTAIN
GARCIA?
>> OH, YEAH.
DEFINITELY.
LIKE I SAID, I'M SPEECHLESS.
I'M KIND OF SHOCKED, BELIEVE IT
OR NOT.
AFTER ALL OF THE THINGS WE DID
IN THE LAST YEAR, THIS IS
PROBABLY THE MOST CHAOTIC ONE.
I DON'T KNOW.
>> THEY WANTED TO GET YOU BACK.
WE HAVE A LITTLE BIT OF BREAKING
NEWS HERE, EVERYBODY.
ALLIE, CAN WE SHOW WHAT YOUR DAD
MISSED.
THE FIRST TOOTH HAS FALLEN OUT.
LOOK AT THAT TOOTH GONE.
LOOK AT THAT.
AND NOW, YOU'RE HERE FOR IT.
AND, MARK, I KNOW YOU LIKE
PLAYING BOARD GAMES WITH YOUR
DAD.
ARE YOU READY TO TAKE HIM ON IN
MONOPOLY?
WHAT DID YOU SAY TO ME
BACKSTAGE?
THIS IS A CHRISTMAS --
>> MIRACLE.
>> IT'S A CHRISTMAS MIRACLE.
IT REALLY IS.
BACK TO YOU GUYS.
>> SO GREAT TO SEE THAT FAMILY
TOGETHER AGAIN.
ENJOY YOUR HOLIDAY.
ENJOY YOUR CHRISTMAS.
ENJOY EVERY, SINGLE MINUTE OF
IT.
YOU MADE OUR FRIDAY HERE AT
"GMA."
CAPTAIN GARCIA, HAVE A GREAT
DAY.
>> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU ALL.
THANK YOU.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>>> GOOD MORNING, THERE WILL BE
EXTRA SECURITY AT TWO SCHOOLS
THIS MORNING.
SHERIFF'S DEPUTIES WILL BE ON
CAMPUS IN CUPERTINO AFTER A BOMB
THREAT FORCED THE CLOSURE OF
BOTH SCHOOLS YESTERDAY.
GRAFFITI SCRAWLED ON A WALL AT
ANOTHER HIGH SCHOOL CLAIMED
THERE WAS A BOMB AT MONTEVISTA
AND THREATENED TO KILL A
SPECIFIC TEACHER THERE.
THE TEACHER REMAINS UNDER POLICE
PROTECTION.
LET'S SEE HOW THE MORNING
COMMUTE LOOKS LIKE.
>> IT'S NOT BAD AT ALL.
MacARTHUR MAZE, PAST THE
BERKELEY CLUE, HERE IS WHAT
YOU'LL FIND.
METERING LIGHTS ARE ON AND
TRAFFIC BACKED TO THE
OVERCROSSING.
ELSEWHERE, WESTBOUND 84 AT
UNIVERSITY WE HAVE A STAULD
STALL BLOCKING THE LANE NUMBER
TWO, SECOND LANE FROM THE LEFT
AND SOUTH 101 MILLBRAE EARLIER
AN ACCIDENT.
>> IT IS COLD OUT THERE.
WE'LL CHECK IN WITH MI
>>> WELCOME BACK.
LIVE LOOK AT LIVE DOPPLER RADAR.
RED AND LIGHT BLUE, LIGHT RAIN
AND THAT IS THE BEST WE CAN DO.
COOL CONDITIONS AND WE ARE STILL
IN THE 30s AND 40s ON OUR WAY TO
40s AND LOW 50s.
SCATTERED SHOWER AFTER THIS
♪ BETTER SAVE UP 'CAUSE I NEED A
MAN ♪
>>> LOOK OUT THERE ON THE BIG
SCREEN RIGHT THERE.
OLIVIA NEWTON-JOHN, AND JOHN
TRAVOLTA.
WE ALL REMEMBER THEM FROM
"GREASE."
THEY'RE BACK TOGETHER AGAIN,
REUNITING FOR A HOLIDAY ALBUM.
THEY'RE GOING TO BE HERE MONDAY.
CAN'T WAIT FOR THAT ON MONDAY.
GOOD MORNING, AMERICA.
A CHEERFUL CROWD HERE IN TIMES
SQUARE.
SO GREAT TO HEAR ROBIN EARLIER
TODAY.
AMY ROBACH HERE.
LARA IS OFF.
AND RACHEL SMITH IS HERE.
HOPE YOU HAD FUN.
>> I HAD A BLAST.
>>> D.J. SUGAR RAY, IN THE
HOUSE.
>> THERE HE IS.
>> TERRIFIC.
>> I CAN'T THINK OF A BETTER WAY
TO GET INTO THE WINTER HOLIDAY
MOOD.
"SUMMER LOVIN'."
I DON'T HAVE TO SING IT.
>>> ALSO AHEAD, IT'S THE SEASON
TO GET ENGAGED.
BUT FOR STAR STYLIST RACHEL ZOE,
REVEALING THE MOST DAZZLING
ENGAGEMENT RINGS FOR EVERY
BUDGET.
>> VERY TRUE.
>>> ALSO, TAKE A LOOK AT THIS.
IT'S ON A LOT OF HOLIDAY WISH
LISTS RIGHT NOW.
GOOD MORNING, AMERICA.
JANE BUCKINGHAM IS JOINING US
WITH THE HOTTEST HOLIDAY GIFT.
THAT IS COOL.
OKAY, THAT IS COOL.
>> FROM YOUR iPAD?
>> APPARENTLY.
TEENS AND TWEENS TAKE NOTE.
>> IT MAY BE THURSDAY, GANG.
>> ALL RIGHT.
>>> RICHARD BLAIS IS HERE THIS
MORNING.
GOOD MORNING, RICHARD.
THE HOLIDAY PARTIES THAT ARE
FREE.
>> EVERYBODY'S IN THE POOL.
>> EGGNOG.
MOCKTAILS.
>> MOCKTAILS.
VERY MOCK.
>> ONE FOR FROSTY THERE.
>> ALL OF THESE RECIPES HE'S
GOING TO HAVE WILL BE AT
GOODMORNINGAMERICA.COM.
>> THIS IS HALF AND HALF,
SPRITE, AND CHERRY JUICE.
IT TASTES A LOT BETTER THAN IT
SOUNDS.
>> GO AHEAD.
>> IT'S A KID'S EGGNOG.
>> YEAH.
>> LIKE A FLOAT.
>> THAT'S LIKE A FLOAT.
A FLOAT.
>> IT'S DELICIOUS.
IT'S DELICIOUS.
SHOCKINGLY.
>> RACHEL, YOU HAVE TO PUT THE
DRINK DOWN AND GET TO WORK.
>> OKAY.
>>> THIS IS NOT A BAD GIG.
THE HOLIDAYS ARE ONE OF THE MOST
POPULAR TIMES OF THE YEAR TO GET
ENGAGED.
IF YOU'RE THINKING ABOUT SAYING
I DO, YOU'LL DEFINITELY WANT TO
CHECK OUT THESE MUST-HAVE
ENGAGEMENT RINGS.
SUPERSTAR STYLIST, RACHEL ZOE,
CHOSE SOME OF HER FAVORITE
ENGAGEMENT BLING, TO
GIVE EVERY WOMAN A TASTE FOR RED
CARPET GLAMOUR THAT SHE'S KNOWN
FOR.
FOR THE 411 ON FASHION, RACHEL
ZOE IS THE HOTTEST STYLIST IN
HOLLYWOOD.
WHETHER IT'S THE RUNWAY, ON TV,
ONLINE.
>> A GREAT, LITTLE MOD '60s
MINIDRESS.
>> Reporter: IN PRINT.
SHE'S A STAR IN DEMAND BY
CELEBRITY FASHIONISTAS,
EVERYWHERE.
BUT CLOTHES DON'T ONLY MAKE THE
LOOK.
THERE'S JEWELRY, TOO.
AND ESPECIALLY NOW, AT THE
HOLIDAYS, WHEN IT'S THE PRIME
SEASON FOR ENGAGEMENT.
>> THIS IS THE WOMAN WHO REALLY
WANTS SOMETHING COMPLETELY
DIFFERENT THAN YOUR TRADITIONAL
KIND OF ENGAGEMENT RING.
>> Reporter: DIAMONDS MAY BE A
GIRL'S BEST FRIEND.
BUT RACHEL ADORES PLATINUM.
>> IT DOESN'T SCRATCH.
IT DOESN'T TARNISH.
IT HOLDS THE STONE.
I THINK PLATINUM'S FOREVER.
I'M A PLATINUM GIRL.
>> Reporter: AS A SPOKESPERSON
FOR PLATINUM GUILD USA, RACHEL
HAS A UNIQUE TAKE ON HER
MUST-HAVE.
PRICELESS AND PRICEY JEWELS,
STARTING FROM AROUND $1,600 UP
TO $45,000.
>> EVERYBODY HAS A DIFFERENT
BUDGET.
YOU SHOULD SAVE UP FOR THAT
REALLY, ONE SPECIAL PIECE.
>> Reporter: THIS SEASON,
RACHEL'S RECOMMENDATION INCLUDES
DECO RINGS.
>> YOU CAN HAVE A SMALLER STONE.
AND THE DECO, PLATINUM SETTING
AROUND IT.
AND FILL IT WITH PAVE DIAMONDS.
>> Reporter: THIS IS AWESOME.
IT'S PROBABLY MY FAVORITE.
>> IT'S OBVIOUSLY IN PLATINUM.
SET IN DIAMONDS.
>> Reporter: IT'S OKAY TO WEAR
IT EVERY DAY?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
WEAR IT TO THE SUPERMARKET.
WEAR IT TO SCHOOL.
I FEEL LIKE JEWELRY'S MEANT TO
BE WORN.
>> Reporter: I WANT TO PUT ALL
OF THEM ON.
>> I DO SOMETIMES.
JUST SAYING, THAT'S THE BEAUTY
OF MY JOB.
I'LL SIT THERE IN A BATHROBE AND
PUT ON EVERYTHING.
THE KEY IS TO HAVE FUN WITH IT
AND WEAR WHAT YOU FEEL BEST IN.
>> NOT A BAD ASSIGNMENT, RIGHT?
I LIKED THAT ONE.
IT WAS A BAND WITH TONS AND TONS
OF BLING.
I SEE YOU'RE STARTING SOME BLING
YOURSELF, SAM.
>> WE WENT WITH THE SIMPLE BAND
FOR THE ENGAGEMENT RING.
>> I LOVE IT.
CONGRATS.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>>> WHY DON'T WE GET A FINAL
CHECK OF THE WEATHER.
>> WE'LL SHOW YOU WHAT'S GOING
ON OUTSIDE RIGHT NOW.
WE'LL START WITH YOUR TWITTER
AND FACEBOOK PICTURES THAT LET
US KNOW WHAT EVERYTHING LOOKS
LIKE ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO KNOW WHAT IT
LOOKS LIKE IN WAUSAU UNLESS
YOU'RE THERE.
OR YOU SEE THAT PICTURE.
DENVER, A GORGEOUS SKY SHOT.
HERE COMES THE THREE LOWS ACROSS
THE WEEKEND.
THIS BEGINS OUR PATTERN SHIFT,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
WE'RE GETTING SOME MOISTURE
MOVING ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
IN THE AREAS SHADED IN BLUE AND
THE MAGENTA COLOR.
THE EAST COAST DOESN'T GET THAT
YET.
IT WILL BY THE TIME WE GET TO
SUNDAY AND NEXT WEEK.
ENJOY TODAY AND TOMORROW BECAUSE
THOSE TEMPERATURES ARE GOING TO
BE ABSOLUTELY BEAUTIFUL.
IT IS FINALLY WARMING UP A
LITTLE BIT IN THE DEEP SOUTH.
YOU'LL GET A COUPLE DAYS OF
WARMER TEMPERATURES.
THAT'S A GOOD THING.
>>  ALL THAT WEATHER WAS BROUGHT
TO YOU BY BP.
>>> IT IS TIME FOR US TO DO A
LITTLE UPDATE, BY THE WAY, ON
OUR BELIEVE CAMPAIGN WITH
MACY'S.
TIME IS RUNNING OUT TO GET THE
LETTERS TO SANTA.
WE'RE ACTUALLY CLOSING IN ON OUR
GOAL FOR THE MACY'S BELIEVE
CAMPAIGN.
TODAY, BY THE WAY, IS A VERY
SPECIAL DAY BECAUSE IT'S MACY'S
NATIONAL BELIEVE DAY.
IT'S AN IMPORTANT DAY.
AND YOU CAN HELP OUT A LOT
TODAY.
WE'LL TELL YOU MORE ABOUT THAT
IN JUST A SECOND.
WHAT EXACTLY YOU'RE HELPING OUT
WITH.
ABC'S ABBIE BOUDREAU WITH A
STORY ON HOW THESE LETTERS
REALLY CAN HELP.
HERE'S JUST ONE EXAMPLE.
>> Reporter: FOR 4-YEAR-OLD
BRANDON, THE SOUND OF THESE FIRE
ALARMS AND SIRENS THIS MORNING
AREN'T JUST A SURPRISE.
THEY'RE A DREAM COME TRUE.
THIS YOUNG BOY IS A LIVING
MIRACLE.
SINCE BIRTH, HE HAS NOT HAD
WORKING KIDNEYS.
INSTEAD, HE SUFFERED THROUGH
PAINFUL AND GRUELING DAILY
DIALYSIS, JUST TO STAY ALIVE.
>> THIS IS WHAT HE WANTED.
HE WANTED TO BE A FIREMAN.
>> IS THAT A FIREMAN JACKET?
>> Reporter: IT'S BEEN HIS WISH
AS LONG AS HIS FAMILY CAN
REMEMBER.
>> I THINK IT'S TIME TO GO TO
WORK.
LET'S GET DRESSED.
>> WHERE IS HIS HELMET?
>> Reporter: AND TODAY, THAT
WISH WILL BECOME A REALITY.
HE'S JOINING THE FIRE
DEPARTMENT.
WHY THE TEARS?
>> BECAUSE HE'S BEEN THROUGH A
LOT.
YOU KNOW?
AND THE FACT THAT HE'S HERE WITH
US TODAY IS AWESOME.
>> Reporter: BRANDON'S ADVENTURE
BEGINS WITH A FIRE TRUCK RIDE.
THEN, A HELICOPTER TOUR OF THE
FIRE DISTRICT.
HAVE YOU EVER BEEN UP IN A
HELICOPTER BEFORE?
>> YEAH.
FOR MEDICAL REASONS.
>> Reporter: THIS TIME, NOT A
MEDEVAC TAKING HIM TO THE
HOSPITAL.
BUT A JOYRIDE, BRINGING BRANDON
JOY AND, WELL, EVENTUALLY, A
NAP.
BUT FOR ONE SPECIAL BYSTANDER,
BRANDON'S UNCLE, ALL OF THIS
ISN'T JUST ABOUT GRANTING A
WISH.
IT'S ABOUT SAVING A LIFE.
AND YOU'RE PLAYING A REAL
SPECIAL PART IN ALL OF THIS,
RIGHT?
>> I'M THE ACTUAL DONOR.
AND I'VE DECIDED TO COME FORTH
WITH THIS AFTER SEEING WHAT HE'S
BEEN GOING THROUGH.
>> Reporter: HE WILL SOON BE
GIVING THE ULTIMATE GIFT, ONE OF
HIS KIDNEYS, TO HIS NEPHEW,
BRANDON.
BUT TODAY ISN'T ABOUT HOSPITALS.
IT'S ABOUT HOPE.
AND A WISH COME TRUE FOR THE
HAPPIEST LITTLE FIREFIGHTER
EVER.
FOR "GOOD MORNING AMERICA,"
ABBIE BOUDREAU, ABC NEWS, LOS
ANGELES.
>> AND THAT'S THE KIND OF THING
THESE LETTERS CAN DO.
THANKS, MACY'S.
BY THE WAY, A LITTLE DRUMROLL,
AS WE TELL YOU.
IT'S INCREDIBLE.
THE TOTAL, 744,838 LETTERS.
>> THAT'S AWESOME.
>> THAT HAS TRANSLATED INTO
DOLLARS SINCE MACY'S IS KICKING
IN A DOLLAR FOR EVERY LETTER.
IT'S NATIONAL BELIEVE DAY.
THEY'RE GOING TO GRANT 70 WISHES
ACROSS THE COUNTRY TODAY.
BUT ALSO, THEY'RE GOING TO
DOUBLE EVERY LETTER THAT IS
STAMPED AND COLLECTED IN STORES
TODAY.
MACY'S IS GOING TO GIVE $2 A
LETTER.
SO, YOU'VE GOT TO HELP TODAY
BECAUSE YOU'RE REALLY GOING TO
MAKE A LOT OF EXTRA WISHES COME
TRUE.
>> THAT'S TERRIFIC.
YOU GO TO MACY'S.
YOU SEE THE BIG, RED MAILBOX.
YOU DO YOUR PART.
THAT'S FANTASTIC.
THAT IS GREAT.
AND THANKS IN ADVANCE FOR ALL OF
YOU.
FOR MORE ON THE BELIEVE
CAMPAIGN, GOODMORNINGAMERICA.COM
ON YAHOO!
>>> COMING UP, HOLIDAY MUST-GET
GIVEAWAYS FOR ALL YOUR TEENS AND
TWEENS.
EVERYTHING ON YOUR LIST.
STAY WITH US.
>>> ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE COUNTING DOWN TO CHRISTMAS
THIS MORN.
GREAT GIFT IDEAS FOR TEENS AND
TWEENS AND SAM CHAMPION.
THEY'RE ALL GOING TO LOVE THEM.
>> I FEEL LIKE TEENS AND TWEENS.
>> THE HOTTEST, NEW GADGETS,
TRENDY.
ALL OF THE ITEMS FOR YOU, AND A
KARAOKE MACHINE, THAT RACHEL AND
AMY WILL BE SINGING IN A MOMENT.
LET'S GET STARTED NOW.
>> JOINING US NOW IS THE TREND
FORECASTER AND CEO OF TRENDERA,
JANE BUCKINGHAM.
AND SHE HAS ALL OF THE GIFTS WE
NEED TO KNOW ABOUT THIS YEAR.
BRING IT ON.
>> ALL RIGHT, SO THIS IS
FANTASTIC.
THIS IS THE ROVER SPY TANK.
PERFECT TO SPY ON YOUR LITTLE
SISTER, WHAT'S GOING ON IN THE
OTHER ROOM.
WHAT HAPPENS IS THAT, YOU
CONTROL IT FROM YOUR iPAD.
AND THEN, WHAT HAPPENS IS THAT,
IT HAS A CAMERA ON IT.
>> WE'RE LOOKING.
>> YOU DRIVE IT.
>> EXACTLY.
>> WE'RE LOOKING NOW AT THE VIEW
THAT THE ROVER IS PROVIDING.
>> YES.
YOU CAN GO ALL THE WAY AROUND.
>> THERE YOU GO.
>> WE'RE SAYING HI TO EVERYBODY
IN THE STUDIO.
WE CAN COME BACKWARDS.
IT HAS HEADLIGHTS.
AND YOU CAN EVEN TALK THROUGH IT
AND SCARE SOMEBODY.
READY?
I'M TRYING NOT TO CRASH IT INTO
ANYBODY.
IT'S ONLY $89.99.
UNDER 100 BUCKS.
AND A GREAT THING FOR A TEEN OR
TWEEN TO PLAY WITH.
>> IF YOU'RE A LITTLE BROTHER,
THIS IS GOLD TO YOU, TO ANNOY
YOUR BIG SISTER OR BROTHER.
>> PERFECT.
AND RIGHT BEHIND YOU, THIS IS
GREAT, TEENS AND TWEENS TODAY,
HAVE TAKEN OVER INSTAGRAM.
THERE'S A MILLION TWEENS.
IF YOU TAKE 40 OF YOUR PICTURES
AND YOU TURN IT INTO A POSTER.
SO, WE HAVE A NICE MIX OF ME AND
YOU GUYS.
AND IT'S ONLY $25.
>> THAT'S FANTASTIC.
MY NIECE IN HER DORM ROOM HAS
THE PICTURES OF HER SORORITY
SISTERS UP.
YOU CAN DO IT ON ONE BIG
PICTURE.
>> WE SHOULD WARN YOU.
WE'VE NOT HAD A SUCCESSFUL
HELICOPTER LANDING ON THIS
PROGRAM.
>> I MAY NOT BE YOUR FIRST ONE.
THIS IS THE UFO SKYWRITER.
YOU CAN PUT A LITTLE SAYING ON
IT.
>> YEAH, YEAH.
>> IT SAYS "GMA."
YOU CAN SAY MARRY ME.
READY?
>> GO AHEAD.
>> CAN YOU SEE IT?
>> READY?
YOU WANT TO -- HERE.
>> THERE YOU GO.
THEY'RE PRETTY COOL.
AND THAT'S ONLY $35.
>> NOW, BE FREE.
OH.
>> OKAY, STILL, WE HAVE NOT HAD
A SUCCESSFUL HELICOPTER.
>> I'M NOT GOING FLYING WITH
YOU.
>> IN PREFERRED CAPTIVITY.
THANK YOU.
>> THESE ARE A LOT EASIER TO
USE.
THEY'RE HEADPHONES THAT YOU
DECORATE YOURSELF.
YOU CAN DESIGN THEM.
WRITE WHATEVER YOU WANT.
AND THEN, AGAIN, A GREAT GIFT.
A LITTLE UNDER $100.
>> OKAY.
ALL PROLOGUE TO AMY AND RACHEL.
>> THIS IS A KARAOKE MACHINE.
WHAT'S THE KEY OF E?
>> WHAT ARE THE WORDS?
>> SING.
>> YOU KNOW THE WORDS.
>> BY THE RECORD MACHINE.
>> YOU GOT IT.
>> HE MUST HAVE BEEN ABOUT 17.
>> YOU PUT THE HEADPHONES ON.
>> IF YOU WERE A TEENAGER,
NOTHING WOULD MAKE YOU HAPPIER
THAN TO SING THIS.
♪ PLAYING MY FAVORITE SONG IT
WOULDN'T BE LONG ♪
♪ YEAH, ME I COULD TELL IT
♪ HE WAS WITH ME YEAH, ME
♪ SINGING I LOVE ROCK 'N' ROLL
PUT ANOTHER DIME IN THE JUKEBOX,
BABY ♪
>> SING IT RIGHT HERE.
>> EVEN WHEN YOU SAY YOU'RE NOT
GOING TO SING, WHEN SOMEONE
TURNS ON KARAOKE.
>> IT'S HARD NOT TO.
>> YOU CAN'T HELP IT.
>> THEY HAVE IT IN BLUE.
THEY HAVE IT IN PINK.
AND YOU CAN GIVE IT TO A BOY, A
GIRL, WHOEVER.
>> WE SHOULD APOLOGIZE FOR THAT.
>> GO TO GOODMORNINGAMERICA.COM
ON YAHOO!
GET ALL OF THE DETAILS ON ALL
THE GREAT GIFTS WE JUST SAW.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
♪ YEAH, ME
>> SING US INTO BREAK.
>>> COMING UP, RICHARD BLAIS.
♪ PUT ANOTHER DIME IN THE
JUKEBOX, BABY ♪
>> YOU ALWAYS GET OUT OF IT.
ANOTHER DIME IN THE
JUKEBOX, BABY ♪
>> YOU ALWAYS GET OUT OF IT.
>>> THERE HE IS.
A LITTLE D.J. SUGAR RAY.
HELPING US COUNT DOWN TO
CHRISTMAS WITH
OUR 12 DAYS OF CHRISTMAS IS
COOKING RIGHT NOW.
WE'RE WITH TOP CHEF RICHARD
BLAIS.
MAKING FANTASTIC MOCKTAILS THIS
MORNING.
WHAT IS THIS ONE?
>> THIS ONE IS A MEXICAN HOT
CHOCOLATE.
IT HAS A LITTLE CINNAMON IN IT.
SO, IT'S PERFECT FOR THE
HOLIDAYS.
AND WE'RE TOPPING IT WITH GROUND
UP RED HOT CANDY.
THE RED HOTS HAVE A LITTLE
BIT -- YOU HAVE TO HAVE A
WHIPPED CREAM MUSTACHE.
IT'S GOOD, RIGHT?
IT HAS THE RED HOTS CRUSHED UP
ON THAT.
>> YOU'RE GOING TO USE SOME
CHRISTMAS CANDIES THROUGHOUT ALL
OF THIS.
AND THIS IS GOING TO BE
SOMETHING.
LAMB CHOPS, WITH CANDY CANE.
BUT, THERE'S A LITTLE PREP
FIRST.
>> LAMB CHOPS WITH CANDY CANE.
THIS IS A BIG, MEATY LAMB CHOP.
REALLY GOOD FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
AND YEAH, THE CHALLENGE IS, YOU
HAVE ALL OF THIS STUFF LAYING
AROUND FROM THE HOLIDAYS.
CAN YOU ACTUALLY USE IT, RECYCLE
IT, COOK WITH CANDY CANES AND
GINGERBREAD AND CHRISTMAS TREE,
AND ROSEMARY.
ROSEMARY AND LAMB IS SYNONYMOUS.
>> WHAT ELSE ARE YOU PUTTING ON?
>> SOME SALT.
SOME OLIVE OIL.
AND MINT AND CORIANDER.
SOME FENNEL SEEDS.
>> YEAH.
>> SOME BLACK PEPPER.
>> HOW LONG DO YOU LET THIS SIT?
>> IF YOU HAVE AN HOUR, IT'S
FINE.
IF IT'S 30 MINUTES, THAT'S FINE.
OVERNIGHT, THAT'S FINE, TOO.
>> THAT'S WHAT IT LOOKS LIKE
AFTER IT'S BEEN SITTING FOR A
WHILE.
>> HAS ALL THAT MARINADE IN IT.
AND THEN A HOT GRILL.
THIS IS GREAT THE CAST IRON
GRILL.
YOU CAN GET THE FLAVOR FROM THE
CAST IRON.
THAT'S WHAT YOU WANT.
YOU WANT THAT SOUND RIGHT THERE.
DOESN'T IT LOOK DELICIOUS?
>> IT'S DELICIOUS AS WELL.
YOU WANT TO HEAR THAT SIZZLE.
THAT WAY YOU KNOW IT'S COOKING.
>> HOW LONG WILL THEY TAKE ON
THAT GRILL?
>> THIS WILL PROBABLY TAKE
20 MINUTES OR SO.
YOU CAN THROW THEM ON THE GRILL.
THEY'RE FINISHING UP.
THROW THEM ON THE GRILL, POP
THEM IN THE OVEN, FINISH THEM IN
THE OVEN.
THAT'S THE ROSEMARY.
THAT'S COOKING WITH A WREATH OR
CHRISTMAS TREE.
AND THEN, WE'RE MOVING OVER TO
SOME OF OUR MORE CREATIVE SIDES.
POLENTA.
POLENTA'S GREAT.
WE HAVE POLENTA.
AND WHAT WE'VE DONE IS VERY
SIMPLY --
WHERE IS IT AT?
WE HAVE PULVERIZED THE
GINGERBREAD MAN.
WE HAVE.
>> THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
>> GINGER, ALL OF THE FLAVORS,
AROMATIC.
>> YOU JUST SPRINKLE IT ON TOP.
>> THIS COULD BE --
>> I WILL SAY, HE GAVE HIS LIFE
SO THAT WE COULD ENJOY.
WE THANK YOU FOR IT.
THE SACRIFICE.
>> AND THEN, OF COURSE, CREAMED
SPINACH.
THIS IS MY FAVORITE RECIPE HERE.
CREAMED SPINACH COOKED WITH
EGGNOG.
EGGNOG HAS NUTMEG IN IT.
CREAMED SPINACH HAS NUTMEG IN
IT.
A NICE WAY TO REUTILIZE YOUR
WREATH, YOUR CHRISTMAS TREE,
YOUR GINGERBREAD MAN.
AND THE CANDY CANE.
CAN YOU HELP ME OUT?
HERE WE GO.
WE'RE GOING TO SHAVE SOME CANDY
CANE ON TOP OF THE LAMB.
HERE WE GO.
LIKE PARMESAN IN A NICE ITALIAN
RESTAURANT.
LAMB AND MINT GOES TOGETHER
REALLY WELL.
>> AND A LITTLE BIT HERE.
>> SHAVED IT.
>> ALL RIGHT.
AND THIS IS VERY LOCAL, OF
COURSE.
>> I LOVE THAT.
GREAT STUFF.
YOU CAN GET ALL OF THE RECIPES,
ALSO THE MOCKTAILS AT
GOODMORNINGAMERICA.COM ON YAHOO!
WE'RE GOING TO BE RIGHT BACK.
I NEED SOME SILVERWARE, NOW.
AT
GOODMORNINGAMERICA.COM ON YAHOO!
WE'RE GOING TO BE RIGHT BACK.
I NEED SOME SILVERWARE, NOW.
>>> THERE'S FROSTY RIGHT THERE.
THANKS TO FROSTY.
THANKS TO RICHARD BLAIS.
OUR THANKS TO D.J. SUGAR RAY
RIGHT THERE.
WHAT A GREAT KICKOFF TO THE
WEEKEND.
STAY TUNED.
WE HAVE "GMA LIVE!" COMING UP.
>> THAT, WE DO.
>> 15 MINUTES.
STICK AROUND FOR THAT.
>> THANKS FOR WATCHING.
>> HAVE A GOOD WEEKEND,
EVERYONE.
.
>> THANKS FOR WATCHING.
>> HAVE A GOOD WEEKEND,
EVERYONE.
>>> GOOD MORNING, I'M KRISTEN
SZE.
EMPLOYEES ARE WAITING TO HEAR
ABOUT PLANS FOR THE COMPANY'S
PLANS TO RELOCATE AFTER A FIRE.
THE FAST MOVING FIRE SPREAD
THROUGH THE PLANT YESTERDAY
AFTERNOON.
NOBODY WAS HURT BUT THE FLAMES
DESTROYED NEARLY EVERYTHING
INSIDE.
MIKE HAS A CHECK W OF THE
FORECAST.
>> CHECK OUT LIVE DOPPLER 7-HD.
SHOWING RADAR RETURNS, MOST OF
IT IS NOT MAKING IT TO THE
GROUND.
IT'S TOO DRY.
IT'S MOVING THROUGH AND CLOUDS
WILL BRAY OPEN TO SUNSHINE.
40s AND 50s.
BETTER CANS OF LIGHT RAIN
TOMORROW AND SUNDAY.
>> EARLIER ACCIDENT 80 WESTBOUND
AT ALBANY, VERY SLOW TRAFFIC
PAST GOLDEN GATE FIELDS AND
SNEAKING INTO THE MacARTHUR
MAZE.
PAST THE CAL DID HE KOL COULD
THE
ANNOUNCER: IT'S "LIVE WITH KELLY
AND MICHAEL."
TODAY, STAR OF THE DRAMA "THE
IMPOSSIBLE," EWAN MCGREGOR.
AND FROM THE SERIES "SCANDAL,"
AND THE NEW FILM "DJANGO
UNCHAINED," KERRY WASHINGTON.
PLUS WE WRAP UP "LIVE'S" HOLIDAY
HITS WEEK FROM A PERFORMANCE
FROM JACKIE EVANCHO.
ALL NEXT ON THE EMMY-AWARD
WINNING "LIVE."
[CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
DISNEY-ABC DOMESTIC TELEVISION]
ANNOUNCER: NOW H