HOW MUCH OF THE MOVIE TOOK A
PAGE FROM THEIR OWN MARRIAGE.
>>> AND ALICIA KEYS IS
PERFORMING HER BRAND-NEW HIT
LIVE AND TELLING YOU ABOUT
COLLABORATING WITH EVERYONE FROM
NICKI MINAJ TO BRUNO MARS FOR
HER CD CRITICS AND FANS ARE
CALLING HER MASTERPIECE.
♪ JUST ONE TOO MANY
>> Announcer: ALL THAT, "HOT
TOPICS" AND MORE COMING UP LIVE
ON "THE VIEW."
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> WHOO!
>> WELL, HELLO AND WELCOME TO
"THE VIEW."
BARBARA?
>> ANNIVERSARY TO ANNOUNCE.
THIS IS THE 3,500th DAY OF "THE
VIEW."
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> ETCH EVEN EVERY ONE OF THEM.
>> 3,500.
>> EXACTLY.
LIKE 90 DAYS, YOU KNOW, SO WE
WANT TO CELEBRATE A LITTLE BIT.
ALL OF YOU WHO WATCH.
>> WELL, BARBARA --
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> SPEAKING OF THANKING PEOPLE,
WE WANT TO START OFF BY THANKING
TOM CRUISE WHO SENT US ALL THESE
AMAZING DELICIOUS COCONUT CAKES
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
>> SO NICE.
>> BUT, BARBARA, YOU SAY YOU
DIDN'T GET ONE BUT THEN IT TURNS
OUT YOU DID AND THEN WE FOUND
OUT WHAT HAPPENED TO IT AND YOU
WERE OUT OF TOWN AND WHEN THE
CAKE ARRIVED AND SO THE STAFF
MISTAKENLY ATE IT.
THEY FELT REALLY, REALLY BAD
ABOUT IT.
I WANT TO TELL YOU ABOUT THAT --
>> I DIDN'T KNOW YOU WERE GOING
TO DO THIS, HONEST TO GOD.
>> BARBARA HAS BEEN SEARCHING
FOR HER CAKE, RIGHT?
>> REALLY BAD.
>> WHAT IS THAT?
>> WELL, ALL I CAN DO IS GIVE
YOU WHAT THEY'RE OFFERING.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> YOU GOT TO TELL WHAT HAPPENED
WITH THE CAKE.
>> OKAY.
>> WHAT HAPPENED -- THIS IS A
COCONUT CUPCAKE WHICH DOES NOT
MAKE UP FOR IT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> WHAT HAPPENED WAS THAT THE
OTHER DAY ON THE SHOW YOU ALL
THANKED TOM CRUISE WHO IS ALWAYS
VERY GENEROUS AND SENDS US --
THE FOUR OF YOU THANKED TOM
CRUISE AND I THOUGHT, THEY GOT A
CAKE AND I DIDN'T GET A CAKE?
A BIG CAKE?
AND I LIKE TOM CRUISE AND -- I
DIDN'T GET A CAKE?
SO IT TURNS OUT --
>> OH.
>> THAT I DID GET A CAKE, BUT I
WASN'T ON THAT DAY, SO THE STAFF
ATE IT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
THEY NEGLECTED TO TELL ME.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> SO THIS LITTLE PUNY CUPCAKE,
STAFF, I LOVE YOU ALL AND MERRY
CHRISTMAS, BUT I WILL NOT
FORGET.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> BUT DID THEY AT LEAST KEEP
THE LITTLE CARD THAT TOM CRUISE
SENT TO YOU.
>> NO.
>> THEY ATE THAT TOO.
THEY ATE THAT TOO.
>> THEY ATE EVERYTHING.
>> LAST YEAR WE GOT RED VELVET
CAKE.
>> I WAS SO HAPPY LAST YEAR I
JUMPED OVER A COUCH.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> VERY FUNNY.
>> SPEAKING OF FUNNY
WRITER/DIRECTOR JUDD APATOW IS
HERE WITH HIS WIFE LESLIE MANN
WHO STARS IN HIS LATEST MOVIE
"THIS IS 40."
IN THE VERY FIRST SCENE LESLIE'S
CHARACTER IS VERY ANGRY THAT HER
HUSBAND TOOK VIAGRA BEFORE THEY
HAD SEX.
WHY WOULD HE?
WOULD IT BOTHER YOU.
>> VIAGRA IS SUPPOSED TO KEEP
YOU GOING ALL NIGHT LONG.
>> NO, YEAH --
>> NO, BECAUSE IT'S SUPPOSED TO
KEEP YOU GOING.
>> COMMERCIAL THAT SAYS IF THIS
LASTS MORE THAN --
>> FOUR HOURS, 3 HOURS 40
MINUTES TOO LONG.
>> 3 HOURS AND 20 MINUTES TOO
LONG.
I DON'T HAVE ALL NIGHT.
>> I THINK THERE'S SOME SHAME IN
GUYS WHO TAKE IT.
WOULD YOU BE UPSET IF YOUR GUY,
IF HE DRINKS COFFEE TO STAY
AWAKE AND TALK TO YOU OR TAKE
SOMETHING FOR CHOLESTEROL.
>> WHY DO THEY NEED VIAGRA IF
THEY'RE TURNED ON BY YOU?
>> SOMETIMES IF YOU JUST --
THEY'RE TRYING TO MAKE YOU
HAPPY, YOU KNOW, YOU ALWAYS TALK
ABOUT MAKING YOUR MAN HAPPY.
SOMETIMES THEY TAKE IT BECAUSE
THEY CAN'T DO ONE MORE THING.
IT'S LIKE, COME ON!
COME ON!
RISE.
>> SOMETIMES -- THE OTHER SIDE,
THE WOMAN SAYS, WHATEVER, I
DIDN'T HAVE TO DO IT ANYMORE.
NOW HE'S TAKING VIAGRA.
I THINK IT'S BROKEN UP A LOT OF
MARRIAGES.
>> SOME THINGS --
>> BY THE WAY, WHAT IF HE TAKES
VIAGRA AND HE ISN'T DOING IT
WITH YOU.
>> THAT WOULD CAUSE A PROBLEM.
>> ACNE ON HIS BEHIND.
>> TRY TO DO STUFF SHALL TRY TO
DO STUFF -- I WAS TRYING TO
DANCE -- I WAS --
>> DON'T DO IT.
>> I WAS WATCHING THIS AND I'M
LIKE, OKAY, YOU GOT TO TURN THEM
ON.
SO I REMEMBER I WAS TRYING TO
DANCE FOR SAL.
HE SAID IT WOULD BE GREAT IF YOU
DIDN'T WEAR THAT OLD T-SHIRT
WITH THE TACO STAIN ON IT.
I FORGOT.
YOU GOT TO PUT THE ACCESSORIES
ON TOO.
>> THE MOVIE IS ABOUT, YOU KNOW,
LONG -- MARRIED COUPLE -- A LONG
TIME AND JUDD APATOW AND LESLIE
MANN STAR IN THE MOVIES AND
THEIR DAUGHTERS STAR.
YOU'LL MEET THEM AS WELL SO I
WENT BACKSTAGE TO SAY HELLO.
AREN'T YOU TWO SICK OF EACH
OTHER AND THEY BOTH SAID, YEAH.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> THEY'RE COMEDIANS.
>> THIS MOVIE -- OH, WELL, I WAS
GOING TO TELL YOU MORE, BUT WE
HAVE TO GO AND COME BACK WITH
MORE "HOT TOPICS."
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE DOING.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> Announcer: STILL AHEAD, "THIS
IS 40" WRITER/DIRECTOR JUDD
APATOW IS REVEALING IF THIS IS
HIS MID-LIFE CRISIS MOVIE.
AND HIS WIFE AND STAR LESLIE
MANN IS TELLING YOU WHY IT WAS
HER IDEA TO PUT BOMBSHELL MEGAN
FOX IN THE MOVIE.
OW!
SO YOU THINK
SANTA WILL LIKE THESE...
RED AND GREEN M&M'S?
I DON'T KNOW!
I NEVER MET THE GUY!
WHAAAAA!
HE DOES EXIST!
THEY DO EXIST!
UHM... SANTA?
CAN A 30-DAY-OLD
PLUGGABLE FEBREZE
MAKE EVEN THIS OLD CONTAINER
SMELL FRESH?
TAKE A DEEP BREATH.
DESCRIBE THE ROOM
THAT YOU'RE IN.
I THINK JUST LIKE
A BIG, OPEN SPACE.
LIKE I'M HANGING THE SHEETS
ON THE LINE.
AND IT SMELLS
REALLY FRESH, MAN.
LET'S TAKE
YOUR BLINDFOLD OFF.
OH!
[ both laugh ]
SUPER-WEIRD!
OH, IS IT FEBREZE?
YEAH.
OHH, HOW ABOUT THAT?
FEBREZE HAS
ANTI-CLOGGING TECHNOLOGY
THAT KEEPS IT SMELLING FRESH,
EVEN AFTER 30 DAYS.
FEBREZE. BREATHE HAPPY.
And add a packet of Hidden H,
Valley Original Ranch.
It becomes the first thing they
reach for.
Ranch Mashed Potatoes.
Hidden Valley Ranch. Mix it Up.
Just unroll it,
fill, top,
bake, and present.
That must have
taken you forever!
It was really tough.
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Pie Crust.
Let the Making Begin
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Pie Crust.
ONE SQUARE INCH OF
DELICIOUSLY SMOOTH CHOCOLATE
IN CREAMY MILK...
OR RICH DARK.
INCREDIBLE INDULGENCE.
ONE SQUARE INCH OF BLISS.
HERSHEY'S BLISS.
HMM, WE NEED A NEW GAME.
♪
THAT'LL SAVE THE DAY.
SO WILL BOUNTY SELECT-A-SIZE.
IT'S THE SMALLER POWERFUL SHEET.
THE ONLY ONE
WITH TRAP + LOCK TECHNOLOGY.
LOOK! ONE SELECT-A-SIZE SHEET
OF BOUNTY IS 50% MORE ABSORBENT
THAN A FULL SIZE SHEET
OF THE LEADING ORDINARY BRAND.
USE LESS. WITH THE SMALL
BUT POWERFUL PICKER UPPER,
BOUNTY SELECT-A-SIZE.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>>> NOW, THE TRAGEDY OF SANDY
HOOK MADE GUN CONTROL LAWS THE
HOTTEST TOPIC IN AMERICA RIGHT
NOW.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SAYS IT'S A TOP
PRIORITY.
PROMINENT GUN RIGHTS ACTIVISTS
IN CONGRESS ARE CALLING FOR A
NATIONAL DISCUSSION.
WHERE DO YOU GUYS STAND ON IT?
FOR ME THERE'S -- TO ME YOU HAVE
TO SORT OF ISOLATE IT TO ONE
THING AND I SORT OF FEEL LIKE
YOU CAN'T JUSTIFY OWNING AN
ASSAULT RIFLE.
I MEAN IT'S A WEAPON OF MASS
DESTRUCTION.
IT IS NOT -- YOU CAN'T HUNT WITH
IT BECAUSE IT DESTROYS
EVERYTHING THAT YOU POINT AT IT.
IT'S NOT SOMETHING TO GUARD YOUR
HOUSE BECAUSE YOU END UP TAKING
ALL THE PLASTER DOWN.
THERE IS NO EXCUSE FOR ANYONE TO
OWN ONE.
>> TO THAT POINT --
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> TO THAT POINT, THERE'S AN
INTERESTING STORY.
ON THE DAY THESE 20 CHILDREN
WERE KILLED BY THIS AUTOMATIC
RIFLE.
IN CHINA A CHINESE MAN ATTACKED
23 CHILDREN WITH A KNIFE.
ONLY MINOR INJURIES.
ALL THESE CHILDREN IN
CONNECTICUT ARE DEAD AND THESE
CHILDREN IN CHINA HAVE MINOR
INJURIES.
THAT TELLS YOU SO MUCH.
>> LET ME GIVE YOU SOME FACTS
BECAUSE THE PRESIDENT HAS SAID
THIS IS NOT GOING TO -- THAT
THERE'S GOING TO BE A DIFFERENCE
AND THAT THERE ARE THINGS
THEY'RE GOING TO DO AND HE'S
ALREADY HAD MEETINGS MONDAY
AFTERNOON ABOUT THIS ISSUE WITH
HIS ATTORNEY GENERAL, HIS
EDUCATION SECRETARY AND SO FORTH
BUT FEDERAL LAW DOES NOT TRUMP
STATE LAW.
EVEN IF HE MAKES A FEDERAL LAW,
IT IS STILL UP TO THE INDIVIDUAL
STATES.
IN NEW YORK WHERE WE LIVE, WHERE
MAYOR BLOOMBERG HAS BEEN
AGAINST -- HAS BEEN FOR GUN
CONTROL FROM THE VERY BEGINNING,
I THINK NEW YORK I'M READING HAS
THE STRICTEST GUN LAWS IN THE
UNION.
BUT IT DEPENDS ON WHERE YOU'RE
LIVING AND HOW --
>> THE LOWEST CRIME RATE IN ANY
URBAN CENTER IN THIS COUNTRY,
NEW YORK.
>> BUT EVEN IF -- RIGHT NOW THE
PRESIDENT -- THE RHETORIC IS
THERE AND IT'S THE RIGHT
RHETORIC.
CAN HE MAKE A DIFFERENCE?
WILL IT INFLUENCE THE DIFFERENT
STATES?
THAT'S SOMETHING WE HAVE TO SEE.
>> I THINK -- I'M SORRY, SHERRI.
TWO THINGS, I THINK ONE IS WE
SPEAK ABOUT THIS OBVIOUSLY, THE
SERVICES FOR THOSE THAT WERE
SLAUGHTERED ARE GOING ON.
FIRST I WANTED TO MENTION THAT
THE DAY AFTER THIS HAPPENED,
MORE OF THOSE ASSAULT RIFLES AND
WEAPONS WERE SOLD.
>> YEP.
>> SECOND, WE'VE BEEN MORE APT
IN THE SOCIETY TO REMOVE GOD AND
BE SUCCESSFUL AT THAT THAN GUNS
WHEN THEY HURT PEOPLE AND NEED A
REAL REVAMP OF WHAT'S GOING ON
AND BIGGER THAN ANY OF US COULD
DISCUSS TODAY.
I THINK THERE'S A MAJOR, MAJOR
CHANGE THAT NEEDS TO HAPPEN.
>> AND HOW WE GET THERE.
>> I AGREE WITH YOU, ELISABETH.
CHRIS CUOMO WAS TALKING ABOUT
THE CULTURE AND VIDEO GAMES,
MADE TWO, THREE, FOUR OF THEM
WHERE YOU GET POINTS FOR KILLING
COPS.
YOU GET POINTS FOR SHOOTING JUST
REGULAR PEOPLE AND I GO, WE GOT
TO DO SOMETHING AND YOU GO WHAT
CAN EACH OF US DO WITH THESE
VIDEO GAMES THAT ARE BEING SOLD.
>> ADAM LANZA SPENT HOURS
PLAYING "CALL OF DUTY."
ARE YOU FAMILIAR WITH THAT?
>> YES.
>> CALL OF DUTY IS CONTROVERSIAL
BECAUSE -- I JUST HEARD ABOUT
IT.
IN THE GAME YOU'RE SHOOTING
ENEMY SOLDIERS.
YOU'RE NOT SHOOTING CIVILIANS.
>> RIGHT.
>> BUT HE LOVED THIS GAME AND HE
LOVED THE SHOOTING -- WHEN THEY
DISCUSS THIS, IT'S NOT JUST GUN
CONTROL.
IT'S HAVING MORE OPPORTUNITIES
TO UNDERSTAND MENTAL ILLNESS.
IT'S HAVING MORE PLACES WHERE
YOU CAN GO.
>> IT'S A FACTOR.
>> AND SHOULD YOU BAN -- IF
YOU'RE GOING TO ASSAULT BAN
WEAPON, SHOULD YOU BAN VIOLENT
VIDEO GAMES?
>> I THINK THE FIRST THING IS TO
FIND THE THING WHICH DOESN'T
MAKE ANY SENSE, YOU KNOW, PEOPLE
CAN TALK ABOUT, YOU KNOW, THEIR
SECOND AMENDMENT RIGHTS BUT
NO -- NO FOUNDING FATHER WAS
THINKING ABOUT ASSAULT RIFLES.
GET A MUSKET IF YOU'RE REALLY
GOING TO TALK ABOUT THAT, BUT
ASSAULT WEAPONS, NOPE, WE CAN'T
HAVE A TANK.
YOU CAN'T GO BUY A BA SUK KA,
WHY THE HELL CAN YOU BUY A
WEAPON OF MASS DESTRUCTION?
THAT'S WHAT IT IS.
THAT'S THE FIRST THING THAT
SHOULD BE GONE.
>> AGAIN, IT'S UP TO THE STATES.
[ APPLAUSE ]
WE ALL FEEL THE SAME WAY AND
ITS -- HARD FOR US TO SAY THIS
BUT EASY FOR US TO SAY THIS.
WE HAVE STATE LEGISLATURES.
WE HAVE CONGRESSMEN, WE HAVE
SENATORS.
WE HAVE A PRESIDENT AND IT HAS
TO GO AND -- THAT HAS TO GO
BEYOND THIS.
>> IT HAS TO COME FROM US.
>> IT HAS TO GO WITH LETTER
WRITING AND E-MAILING.
>> HOW ABOUT --
>> WHAT I'M SAYING IS YOU'VE GOT
TO MAKE YOUR VOICES KNOWN.
>> WHAT ABOUT --
>> LET ME FINISH.
IF YOU WANT TO CHANGE STATE AND
FEDERAL LAW.
WE CAN TALK HERE ALL WE WANT.
>> IT'S ALL TRUE.
NOW, SHERRI, WHAT -- WHAT DO YOU
WANT TO GIVE TO US?
>> YES, WE SAY -- WE SAY MORE
THAN EVER THIS HOLIDAY
SEASON, WE NEED TO SHOW EACH
OTHER HOW MUCH WE CARE.
TELEFLORA WORKS ONLY WITH A
NETWORK OF LOCAL FLORISTS
OFFERING 100% HAND-ARRANGED,
HAND-DELIVERED FLORAL BOUQUETS
IN KEEPSAKE VASES THAT ARE
PERFECT FOR THE HOLIDAY TABLE
LIKE THIS GORGEOUS VINTAGE-STYLE
MERCURY GLASS.
AND MEMBERS OF OUR STUDIO
AUDIENCE ARE GOING HOME WITH A
$100 TELEFLORA GIFT CARD.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> WHOO!
YAY.
NICE AND BEAUTIFUL.
YEAH, YEAH.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
AND WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH
JUDD APATOW AND LESLIE MANN.
>> Announcer: STILL AHEAD,
ALICIA KEYS IS TAKING THE STAGE
TO PERFORM HER LATEST HIT LIVE
ON OUR STAGE.
[ Female Announcer ] THERE ARE
LOTS OF DIFFERENT WAYS
TO SAY GET WELL
TO YOUR LOVED ONES.
♪
THIS CAME FOR YOU, MOMMY.
[ Female Announcer ]
BUT IT TAKES THE TOUCH
OF KLEENEX® BRAND,
AMERICA'S SOFTEST TISSUE,
TO TURN A GESTURE
INTO A COMPLETE GIFT OF CARE.
[ barks ]
SEND YOUR OWN FREE
KLEENEX® CARE PACK...
FULL OF SOOTHING ESSENTIALS
AT KLEENEX.COM.
KLEENEX®.
AMERICA'S SOFTEST TISSUE.
AH! SO YOU'RE
THE NEW LITTER GENIE, HUH?
MY HUMAN SAYS
YOU GRANTED HER WISH.
NOW SHE DOESN'T
HAVE TO BAG MY BUSINESS
AND BURY IT
IN THE TRASH ANYMORE.
GOOD, CUZ THAT WAS AWFUL.
FOR THE BOTH OF US.
[ Female Announcer ]
INTRODUCING LITTER GENIE,
EASY LITTER DISPOSAL.
THE MAGIC'S INSIDE.
SIMPLY SCOOP THE CLUMP,
DROP IT IN THE FIVE PLY BAG
AND HELP LOCK IN ODORS.
THEN JUST EMPTY
EVERY TWO WEEKS.
AHYWHOOZLE GENIE. YOU JUST
KEEP DOING YOUR BUSINESS
CUZ YOU KNOW
I'M GONNA BE DOING MINE.
MEOW.
[ Female Announcer ]
NEW LITTER GENIE.
YOUR WISH GRANTED.
Plus
The perfecting color
of a BB cream
Equal?
Introducing
the newest beauty trend.
Total Effects CC Cream
C for Color. C for Correction.
[ Female Announcer ]
Fight 7 signs of aging
Flawlessly.
CC what's possible.
♪
Get her 1/3rd carat
diamond earrings
this week only just $29.99.
And save 75 to 80% on
all Fashion Diamonds.
At Kmart.
DELICIOUS HERSHEY'S CHOCOLATEH,
WITH 30% LESS FAT?
HERSHEY'S SIMPLE
PLEASURES CHOCOLATE.
30% LESS FAT, 100% DELICIOUS.
I just served my mother-in-law
your Chicken Noodle soup
but she loved it so much...
I told her it was homemade.
Everyone tells
a little white lie now and then.
But now she wants
my recipe
[ clears his throat ]
[ softly ]
She's right behind me isn't she?
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
[ Female Announcer ]
Almost nothing can dampen
a baby's mood,
when he wakes up dry
in Pampers.
Unlike other diapers,
Pampers has 3 absorbent layers,
for up to 12 hours
of protection overnight,
and more beautiful mornings.
♪
Pampers. Peaceful Nights.
Playful Days.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>>> PRODUCER, DIRECTOR, WRITER,
ACTOR, JUDD APATOW IS THE
BRILLIANT MAN BEHIND SUCH HITS
AS "THE 40-YEAR-OLD VIRGIN,"
"KNOCKED UP," "SUPERBAD,"
"BRIDESMAIDS" AND HIS LATEST
COMEDY "THIS IS 40" STARS HIS
WIFE AS SHE'S IN MANY OF HIS
FILMS, LESLIE MANN.
SHE IS A WOMAN IN THIS WHO IS
NOT READY TO FACE REALITY.
TAKE A LOOK.
>> YOU WANT TO GET A MASSAGE OR
DO SOMETHING FUN?
IT'S -- 40 IS HUGE.
>> I'M TURNING 38.
>> OKAY, 38.
DO YOU REALLY WANT TO BE ONE OF
THOSE LADIES WHO IS JUST SO
INSECURE ABOUT THEIR AGE AND
THEY LIE AND THEN THEY GOT TO
REMEMBER AND IT GETS ALL --
>> YOU DON'T GET IT.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND HOW IT
WORKS.
I DON'T WANT TO SHOP AT OLD LADY
STORES.
I DON'T WANT TO GO TO J. JILL
AND CHICO AND ANN TAYLOR LOFT.
I'M NOT READY YET.
I HAVE TWO MORE YEARS.
>> THAT IS SO INSANE, IT KIND OF
MAKES SENSE.
>> PLEASE WELCOME PRODUCER,
DIRECTOR, WRITER, JUDD APATOW
AND HIS WIFE AND STAR ABSOLUTELY
MANN.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> GOOD.
HOW ARE YOU?
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> HOW ARE YOU?
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> GREETINGS.
>> LISTEN, AS AN ACTOR TOO
BECAUSE YOU DO EVERYTHING ELSE
BUT YOU'RE NOT -- SHE IS.
YOU AIN'T.
>> YES, I CAN'T ACT.
I'M TERRIBLE AT IT.
>> ALL YOU CAN DO IS WRITE AND
DIRECT AND PRODUCE AND OTHER
THINGS.
>> YES.
>> I WANT TO TALK ABOUT VIAGRA.
>> YOU DO?
>> WELL, WELL, WELL.
>> IN THE OPENING OF THE FILM
AND THEY'RE 40 AND LIFE IS
GETTING A LITTLE STWAETTLE STAL
TELL YOU MORE.
YOU ARE SO UPSET BECAUSE HE'S
TAKING VIAGRA.
>> I NEVER EXPERIENCED IT IN
REAL LIFE BUT --
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> CONGRATULATIONS.
>> NO, IT'S TRUE.
>> OKAY.
>> I SHOULD DO IT.
I SHOULD DO IT BECAUSE EVERY
ONCE IN A WHILE YOU GOT TO TURBO
CHARGE IT, RIGHT?
>> NO MATTER WHAT PAUL RUDD
SAID.
>> BUT -- WHEN YOU SEE THE
COMMERCIALS IT'S ENTICING THAT
YOU SHOULD DO IT.
EVERY COMMERCIAL IT'S LIKE THE
SAME REALLY HANDSOME GUY, HE'S
TALL.
HE'S THIN, HE'S IN GREAT SHAPE.
HE'S GOT BEAUTIFUL KIND OF SHORT
GRAY HAIR.
LIKE HE LOOKS LIKE AN ERECTION.
LIKE A PERFECT ERECTION.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> AND IT'S LIKE, COME JOIN ME.
BE LIKE ME.
>> MID-LIFE CRISIS MOVIE, JUDD.
TELL THE TRUTH.
>> I GUESS SO.
I HAVE FOUR MOVIES I DIRECTED
AND TWO HAVE THE NUMBER "40" IN
THE TITLE SO THERE'S SOMETHING
GOING WRONG.
>> HOW OLD ARE YOU?
>> I JUST TURNED 45.
>> OH, YOU'RE WARE OVER THE TOP.
>> I KNOW.
>> SO FUNNY, "THIS IS 40" WHICH
MY HUSBAND AND I, WE LOVED THIS
MOVIE.
IT'S ABOUT A MARRIED COUPLE AND
WE FIRST MEET THIS COUPLE IN
YOUR EARLIER FILM "KNOCKED UP"
AND WE SEE A LITTLE BIT OF THEM
AND NOW IT'S LIKE THEY'RE BOTH
TURNING 40.
BOTH HAVING TROUBLE DEALING WITH
BEING IN THE 40s.
NOW, JUDD, IS SOME OF THIS BASED
ON YOU AND LESLIE?
IS ALL OF IT BASED ON YOU AND
YOUR WIFE GENTLEMAN.
>> WELL, WE LIKE TO SAY A THIRD
OF IT -- A THIRD WE MADE UP AND
A THIRD THAT'S REALLY
EMBARRASSING AND GROSS IS BASED
ON PAUL RUDD'S LIFE.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> BUT THE FACT THAT -- THE
ONE-THIRD -- THE FACT THAT
ONE-THIRD IS COMPLAINING ABOUT
IT BEING STALE, IS THAT THE TWO
OF YOU OR --
>> MADE UP.
>> THAT COMES --
>> REALLY.
>> ARE YOU BROTHER AND SISTER?
>> YEAH, THAT KIND OF HAPPENS,
YOU KNOW, IT'S BEEN -- WE'VE
BEEN TOGETHER FOR 17 YEARS.
>> 17 YEARS.
>> AND --
>> I HAVEN'T.
>> MY FIRST MARRIAGE LASTED THAT
LONG ALSO.
>> WHAT HAPPENED?
>> DIVORCED.
>> WAS THAT A GOOD CALL?
>> NEVER GET JOY.
>> I WOULDN'T BE HERE OTHERWISE.
>> NOT ONLY ARE THE TWO OF YOU
WORKING TOGETHER, DIRECTING,
PRODUCING BUT YOUR TWO DAUGHTERS
ARE IN IT TOO AND WONDERFUL.
IF IT'S TOO MUCH WHY DO YOU KEEP
THE WHOLE FAMILY WITH YOU ALL
THE TIME?
I MEAN, YOU KNOW, YOU COULD USE
SOME SEXY ACTRESS OR --
>> YOU RELY ON HER.
>> USE ANOTHER SEXY ACTRESS.
>> WHO SHOULD I USE?
>> WHO BETTER TO LEARN FROM,
RIGHT?
>> NO, SHE'S THE BEST ACTRESS IN
THE WORLD.
[ APPLAUSE ]
YOU KNOW, SHE'S HILARIOUS AND
SHE ALSO CAN PLAY LIKE REALLY
INTENSE DRAMA AND BE FUNNY AT
EXACTLY THE SAME TIME WHICH I
DON'T THINK ANYBODY ELSE CAN DO.
>> IT'S CHEAPER TO USE YOUR
WIFE, RIGHT?
>> YEAH.
>> SEE.
>> WELL --
>> MAYBE.
WE DON'T KNOW.
>> THE KIDS WORK FOR NOTHING.
>> HE UNDERPAYS THE KIDS.
YES, YOU DO.
>> I PAY THEM JUST THE RIGHT
AMOUNT THAT THE STUDIO DOESN'T
GET MAD AND WE GET TO KEEP ALL
THE MONEY.
>> YOUR DAUGHTER, THERE'S A
SCENE THAT IS REALLY -- SHE'S IN
THE CLOSET AND SHE CAN'T FIND
ANYTHING TO WEAR AND SHE'S
SCREAMING AND THROWS AN "F" NOTE
OUT THERE.
I HEARD IT WAS SOMETHING YOU
TALKED ABOUT WHETHER OR NOT TO
PUT IN THE FILM OR NOT.
>> TO LET HER CURSE OR NOT.
>> THE "F" WORD.
>> THEY DO THAT AT SCHOOL.
>> I THOUGHT YOU WERE SUPPOSED
TO DO IT AT HOME AND NOT AT
SCHOOL.
THAT WAS MY RULE.
>> WELL, YOU HAVE TO MAKE THAT
DECISION.
DO YOU CARE ABOUT CURSING.
WE DID OKAY.
WE CURSE.
WE'RE FINE.
>> HELLO.
>> AS PEOPLE SO IT'S A LITTLE
TRICKY.
A LOT OF THE MOVIE IS ABOUT
TECHNOLOGY --
>> DO YOU CARE IF YOUR GIRLS
CURSE?
>> I ALWAYS JUST SAY YOU SOUND
DUMB WHEN YOU DO IT AND SHE
ALWAYS SAYS, YOU MAKE YOUR WHOLE
LIVING MAKING PEOPLE CURSE.
IT'S HARD FOR ME TO ARGUE.
>> HOW OLD ARE THE KIDS?
>> 11?
>> 15 AND 10.
>> I'M CLOSE.
>> I HAVE HAVE TO ASK YOU.
DO YOU GEM USE AN ENSEMBLE
ALWAYS AND WHEN YOU PLUG OTHER
PEOPLE IN, IS IT AWKWARD BECAUSE
THE WHOLE ENSEMBLE KNOWS HOW TO
WORK TOGETHER OR IS IT STRANGE
OR --
>> I THINK, YOU KNOW, IT'S FUN
BECAUSE WE DO IT IN REHEARSALS.
WE BRING PEOPLE IN.
MEGAN FOX, THIS IS THE FIRST
TIME WE WORKED WITH HER AND
LESLIE AND I SAW HER ON
"SATURDAY NIGHT LIVE" AND SHE
WAS SO FUNNY WE THOUGHT -- PUT
HER IN LIKE A FUNNY PART.
SO SHE CAME IN AND PLAYED AND
SHE WAS SO GREAT AND SHE
INSTANTLY FIT RIGHT IN.
>> FANTASTIC.
>> YOU LIKE WORKING WITH CERTAIN
PEOPLE.
WE LIKE KEEPING CERTAIN PEOPLE
AROUND LIKE THE TWO OF YOU SO
STAY AROUND.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK AFTER THIS.
[ APPLAUSE ]
[ Female Announcer ] Dove
INVITED WOMEN TO TEST THEIR
BODY WASHES WITH PAPER
THAT REACTS LIKE SKIN.
IF OTHERS CAN STRIP THIS PAPER,
IMAGINE HOW HARSH
THEY CAN BE TO YOUR SKIN.
OH MY GOSH.
[ Female Announcer ]
Dove IS DIFFERENT.
ITS NEW BREAKTHROUGH FORMULA
CHANGES EVERYTHING.
NEW Dove.
THIS IS CARE.
Cheese plate?
Cheese plate...nope.
I made something better.
♪
You used the oven?
BOOM
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
Pillsbury Crescents.
Let the making begin.
[ Female Announcer ]
Almost nothing can dampen
a baby's mood,
when he wakes up dry
in Pampers.
Unlike other diapers,
Pampers has 3 absorbent layers,
for up to 12 hours
of protection overnight,
and more beautiful mornings.
♪
Pampers. Peaceful Nights.
Playful Days.
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
DISCOVER THE TEMPTING LAYERS
OF FERRERO ROCHER.
A WHOLE HAZELNUT,
SMOOTH CHOCOLATY CREAM
INSIDE A WAFER SHELL,
COVERED IN MILK CHOCOLATE
AND HAZELNUT PIECES.
♪
FERRERO ROCHER.
MAKE YOUR MOMENTS GOLDEN.
And one wedding,
2 kids,
43 bottles
of Olay Total Effects
And many birthdays later,
Still looks amazing.
Thanks to the trusted
performance of Olay.
>>> THIS IS CARLY FROM GEORGIA.
>> ALICIA KEYS PERFORMS WHEN
"THE VIEW" RETURNS ON ABC.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> YOU WANT TO KILL ME.
>> I DO WANT TO KILL YOU.
>> HOW WOULD YOU DO IT?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
POISON YOU.
I'D POISON YOUR CUPCAKES THAT
YOU PRETEND NOT TO EAT EVERY DAY
AND JUST PUT ENOUGH IN TO JUST
SLOWLY --
>> I LOVE IT.
>> I WOULD ENJOY OUR LAST FEW
MONTHS TOGETHER.
>> ME TOO.
>> BECAUSE YOU'D BE SO WEAK AND
SWEET AND I COULD TAKE YOU BUT
WHILE KILLING YOU.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> OH, MY GOSH.
THAT'S HER AND HER HUSBAND.
>> I KNOW.
>> THAT WAS HYSTERICAL.
>> THIS WAS A CLIP FROM THE NEW
COMEDY "THIS IS 40," AND WE'RE
BACK WITH WRITER/DIRECTOR JUDD
APATOW AND HIS WIFE AND STAR
LESLIE MANN.
YOU WATCHING THIS, DO YOU GUYS
EVER TALK ABOUT HOW YOU WOULD
KILL EACH OTHER?
>> WE'VE NEVER HAD THAT
CONVERSATION --
>> TOO REAL.
>> I DO --
>> HAVE YOU THOUGHT ABOUT IT.
>> I THINK SOMETIMES -- AND I
KNOW JUDD LOVES ME BUT I DO FEEL
LIKE SOMETIMES WHEN I'M ALONE IN
THE HOUSE THAT HE'S PLANNED FOR
ME TO BE ALONE IN THE HOUSE
BECAUSE THEN IT WILL BE EASIER
FOR THE HIT MAN TO COME IN AND
GET ME.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> DO YOU?
>> YES.
>> I KNOW YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
SOMEBODY COMING IN AND HIT ME
AND KNOCK ME OFF.
IT'S SO WEIRD, ISN'T IT?
>> YOU USED TO DO STAND UP.
>> I DID.
>> AND YOU --
>> YOU KNOW, I'VE BEEN MARRIED
SEVERAL TIMES.
THAT OUGHT TO TELL YOU
SOMETHING.
>> YOU KNOW --
>> DID YOU KNOCK YOURS OFF?
>> SOMETIMES IT'S EASIER.
AND THERE ARE TIMES WHEN YOU
REALLY DO WISH THEY WERE DEAD.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> I'M SORRY.
>> WE'RE GOING TO --
GO TO THERAPY NOW.
>> THERAPY.
>> BEFORE WE GOT OFF INTO THAT
VEIN OF KILLING PEOPLE.
I HAVE TO LIST A FEW MOVIES
YOU'VE BEEN INVOLVED IN.
"THE 40-YEAR-OLD VIRGIN,"
"SUPERBAD," "KNOCKED UP,"
"FORGETTING SARAH MARSHALL,"
"BRIDESMAIDS," "ANCHORMAN," I
MEAN THIS JUST JUST GOES AND ON
AND ON AND PEOPLE CALL YOU THE
MAN WHO CHANGED THE FACE OF
COMEDY.
DO YOU THINK THAT?
>> NO, I JUST THINK I'M A FAN OF
COMEDY AND ALL THESE PEOPLE SO
IT'S FUN TO GIVE PEOPLE
OPPORTUNITIES TO SHOW WHAT THEY
CAN DO.
>> WHEN YOU GREW UP WERE YOU FUN
IN I.
>> NO, I THOUGHT I WAS FUNNY.
>> IS HE FUNNY AT HOME.
>> HE'S NOT VERY FUNNY AT HOME.
>> REALLY?
>> NO.
>> YOU DIDN'T HEAR ME BEFORE BUT
I WAS SAYING JUDD DID STAND-UP
SO YOU WEREN'T FUNNY.
HOW DID YOU HAVE THE NERVE TO DO
STAND UP.
>> I THINK I'M FUNNY AT HOME BUT
I LIVE WITH THREE WOMEN.
IT'S LIKE THREE AGES OF THE SAME
WOMAN.
IT'S NOT --
[ LAUGHTER ]
IT'S NOT LIKE THREE DIFFERENT
PEOPLE AND SOMETIMES WE GO OUT
AND WE'LL TALK TO PEOPLE AND
I'LL SAY THINGS AND THEY'LL
LAUGH AND I'LL SAY, LESLIE,
THOSE THINGS I SAY AT HOME ARE
JOKES.
PEOPLE ENJOY THEM SOMETIMES.
>> YOU WROTE FOR JAY LENO,
DIDN'T YOU?
>> WELL, I TRIED TO WRITE FOR
JAY LENO.
>> HOW COME HE DIDN'T USE YOUR
WONDERFUL MATERIAL.
>> I SENT HIM A WHOLE BUNCH OF
JOKES WHEN I WAS 19 YEARS OLD
BECAUSE I HEARD EVERY ONCE IN A
WHILE HE WILL BUY JOKES FOR THE
MONOLOGUE AND HE CALLED AT
MIDNIGHT.
I LIVED WITH MY GRANDMOTHER
BECAUSE I HAD NO MONEY AND MY
GRANDMOTHER SAID, JUDD, JAY LENO
IS ON THE PHONE.
HEY, YOU'RE NOT QUITE RIGHT.
AND THEN HE TOLD ME WHAT WAS
WRONG WITH THEM WHICH IS THE
NICEST THING.
I MEAN WHO CALLS THE GUY WHO
SENDS HIM BAD JOKES, SO I ALWAYS
APPRECIATED THAT AND HE'S A
GREAT FRIEND.
>> PEOPLE WHO DISAGREE WITH
HIM -- WHO DON'T LIKE HIM.
HE CALLS THEM UP.
>> HE LIKES TO.
>> "ANCHORMAN" WAS MENTIONED.
NOW, I LOVE THIS MOVIE.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHY.
THIS -- IT JUST CRACKS ME UP.
I HEAR "ANCHORMAN 2" IS POSSIBLY
HAPPENING.
>> WELL, WILL FERRELL AND ADAM
IS THE DIRECTOR AND THEY'VE
WRITTEN A DRAFT AND WE'LL SHOOT
IT IN MARCH AND ARE VERY
EXCITED.
I CAN'T GIVE AWAY THE DETAILS.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> WELL, PART IN NEW YORK --
>> YOU DON'T KNOW.
WHY DON'T YOU TALK TO EACH
OTHER?
>> AND IT'S EXCITING.
IT'S TOP SECRET.
IT'S LIKE THE NEW "STAR WARS."
WE CAN'T KNOW WHAT BRICK DOES.
NO ONE MUST KNOW.
>> SO ARE YOU WRITING MORE?
YOU'RE 40.
WILL WE SEE YOU AT 50 AND 90.
WHERE DO YOU GO FROM HERE.
>> I THINK IT'S OVER NOW AFTER
17 YEARS.
>> NO, YOU'VE GOTTEN SCARED NOW.
>> DIVORCE COURT IS THE NEXT
ONE.
>> I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE.
>> IF SOMETHING GOOD HAPPENS.
>> WHAT DO YOU DO TO KEEP IT
FRESH?
>> WHAT DO WE DO TO KEEP IT
WELL, EVERY ONCE IN A WHILE WE
TRY TO ESCAPE THE KIDS.
>> WE DO.
>> WONDERFUL --
>> THERE'S A SCENE IN THE MOVIE
WHERE THEY GO AWAY AND THEY HAVE
KIND OF A NONSOBER WEEKEND TO
JUST ENJOY EACH OTHER'S COMPANY
AND WE TRIED TO DO THAT
RECENTLY.
>> HOW DID THAT WORK.
>> IT DIDN'T WORK OUT WELL.
I HAD A PANIC ATTACK AND LESLIE
VOMITED.
AND THEN WE GOT IN BED AND
WATCHED FOUR EPISODES OF "THE
GOLDEN GIRLS" SO THAT'S HOW WE
KEEP IT FRESH
>> THAT'S GOOD.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> IT WAS A PURGING.
>> YOU ARE OUR FAVORITE MARRIED
COUPLE.
YOU GOT TO COME BACK TOGETHER.
WE LOVE YOU.
OH, MY GOSH.
WE WANT TO THANK JUDD APATOW AND
LESLIE MACHINE.
"THIS IS 40" OPENS THIS FRIDAY
AND MEMBERS OF OUR STUDIO
AUDIENCE ARE TAKING HOME A COPY
OF THE SOUNDTRACK OF THIS FILM.
IF YOU'RE MARRIED, GO SEE IT.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> Announcer: BRAD GARRETT'S
TELLING YOU ABOUT HIS TRIUMPHANT
RETURN TO PRIMETIME COMEDY
TOMORROW ON "THE VIEW."
We were so blessed
when we had triplets
If by blessed you mean
freaked out about money
Well
we suddenly noticed
that everything was getting
more expensive
So we switched
to the bargain detergent
but I found myself
using three times more
than you're supposed to
and the clothes still weren't
as clean as with Tide.
So we're back to Tide.
They're cuter in clean clothes.
Thanks honey
Yeah
you suck at folding
[ laughs ]
[ Female Announcer ]
One cap of Tide
gives you more cleaning power
than 6 caps
of the bargain brand.
[ woman ]
That's my tide, What's yours?
YOU'RE NOT USING TOO MUCH
ARE YOU, HON?
♪
NOPE.
[ Female Announcer ]
CHARMIN ULTRA SOFT IS SO SOFT
YOU'LL HAVE TO REMIND
YOUR FAMILY THEY CAN USE LESS.
CHARMIN ULTRA SOFT
IS MADE WITH EXTRA CUSHIONS
THAT ARE SOFT
AND MORE ABSORBENT.
PLUS YOU CAN USE
FOUR TIMES LESS
VERSUS THE LEADING
VALUE BRAND.
DON'T WORRY, THERE'S PLENTY LEFT
FOR YOU DAD.
WE ALL GO.
WHY NOT ENJOY THE GO
WITH CHARMIN ULTRA SOFT?
[ ding! ]
LOSING YOUR CHEX MIX TOO EASILY?
TIME TO DEPLOY
THE BORING-POTATO CHIP
DECOY BAG.
THEN NO ONE WILL WANT TO STEAL
THE DELICIOUSNESS.
[ Male Announcer ] WITH A
VARIETY OF TASTES AND TEXTURES,
ONLY CHEX MIX
IS A BAG OF INTERESTING.
[ Male Announcer ] WITH A
VARIETY OF TASTES AND TEXTURES,
There's a place where the sky is
always blue
and the kids always eat
their vegetables.
Because the salad there is
always served
with the
Original Hidden Valley Ranch.
It's the way Ranch is supposed
to taste.
And try Hidden Valley for
Everything.
It's in the ketchup aisle.
HERSHEY'S MAKES SMILES.
SMILES MAKE MORE SMILES.
WHEN THE CHOCOLATE IS HERSHEY'S.
LIFE IS DELICIOUS.
MY SON LOVES THE APPS
AND MOVIES.
BUT MY DAUGHTER?
VAMPIRE BOOKS.
SHARING...
WHOOH FORGET IT!
WITH OUR WALMART
CREDIT CARD --
SPECIAL FINANCING,
WE CAN GET TWO.
THE KIDS ARE HAPPY.
MY SHOPPING'S DONE.
OUR BUDGET -- UNDER CONTROL.
NOW, LET'S GO.
I KNEW THAT.
RIGHT.
UMPH, I LOVE THAT WOMAN.
[ Male Announcer ]
GET THE SEASONS HOTTEST BRANDS,
LIKE NOOK HD AND HD+.
MAKE AN ELECTRONICS PURCHASE
OF $299 OR MORE
ON YOUR WALMART CREDIT CARD
AND GET NO INTEREST IF PAID
IN FULL WITHIN 12 MONTHS.
AMERICA'S GIFT HEADQUARTERS.
WALMART.
Aunt Sally's
singing again.
It's a tradition,
honey.
[ singing
Christmas carols ]
mmmm.
[ Female Announcer ]
Make new traditions
with Pillsbury Grands!
Cinnamon Rolls.
HI VICTOR!
MOM?
I KNOW YOU GOT TO GO
IN A MINUTE
BUT THIS IS
A REAL QUICK MEAL,
THAT'S PERFECT FOR TWO!
CAMPBELL'S CHUNKY BEEF
WITH COUNTRY VEGETABLES,
POURED OVER RICE!
[ Male Announcer ]
CAMPBELL'S CHUNKY SOUP.
IT FILLS YOU UP RIGHT.
♪
[ Female Announcer ] WITH
ITS RICH, SILKY SMOOTH TASTE
THERE'S MAGIC IN EVERY PIECE
OF DOVE® DARK CHOCOLATE.
♪
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪ THIS GIRL IS ON FIRE
♪ KEEP WALKING ON FIRE
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> OKAY.
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO HEAR VERY
MANY PEOPLE HEAR THIS, BUT THAT
WAS 14-TIME GRAMMY WINNER ALICIA
KEYS.
14.
THE TITLE TRACK
TO HER NEW CD "GIRL ON FIRE"
WHICH A LOT OF CRITICS AND FANS
ARE CALLING HER MASTERPIECE.
MASTERPIECE PLEASE WELCOME
BACK THE ABSOLUTELY FABULOUS
ALICIA KEYS.
♪ WHERE DREAMS ARE MADE OF
THERE'S NOTHING YOU CAN'T DO ♪
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> THAT WAS YOU AND JAY-Z ON
THE CLASSIC"EMPIRE STATE OF
MIND."
ONE OF YOUR GREATEST SONGS EVER.
NOW WITH YOUR NEW CD "GIRL ON
FIRE," GIRL, YOU ARE ON FIRE.
YOUR NEW ALBUM IS GETTING RAVE
REVIEWS.
I WAS LUCKY ENOUGH TO EMCEE YOUR
ANNUAL BLACK BALL AT THE APOLLO,
WHICH RAISED $2.9 MILLION FOR
YOUR KEEP A CHILD ALIVE
FOUNDATION.
IT WAS A FANTASTIC NIGHT, AND
THAT WAS A GOOD NIGHT, YEAH?
>> YES.
DEFINITELY A GOOD NIGHT.
IT WAS INCREDIBLE.
WE ACTUALLY HAD TO RESCHEDULE
THE BALL BECAUSE OF SANDY,
OBVIOUSLY.
IT DISPLACED SO MANY PEOPLE SO
IT WAS INCREDIBLE TO COME
THROUGH NO MATTER WHAT, WHICH I
THINK IS WHAT IS HAPPENING IN
THIS CITY.
EVERYBODY IS REALLY COMING
THROUGH AND --
>> I HEARD YOU WERE HIT PRETTY
HARD BY HURRICANE SANDY.
>> I MEAN NOT AS HARD AS SOME IN
REGARDS TO LOSING A HOME BUT
I -- ALL OF MY EQUIPMENT FOR THE
TOUR AND EVERYTHING WAS BURIED
UNDER LIKE SIX FEET OF WATER BUT
NATURALLY SO MANY PEOPLE LOST
THEIR HOMES AND THAT'S THE MOST
IMPORTANT THING.
>> YOU KNOW, YOU WERE THE
CLOSING PERFORMANCE AT THE
12-12-12 RELIEF CONCERT AND
PERFORMED WITH SIR PAUL
McCARTNEY, BRUCE SPRINGSTEEN,
THE ROLLING STONES.
WHAT WAS IT LIKE FOR YOU.
>> I WAS GOING CRAZY BACKSTAGE.
I COULDN'T BELIEVE IT MUCH THE
FIRST TIME I WENT ON IT WAS
LITERALLY THE ROLLING STONES --
NO, ERIC CLAPTON, THE ROLLING
STONES AND THEN ME.
I WAS LIKE, WHOA.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> I HAD A CRAZY WHOA MOMENT.
IT WAS UNBELIEVABLE AND THEN TO
CLOSE THE SHOW WITH SIR PAUL
McCARTNEY, I MEAN, THAT WAS
JUST -- IT WAS VERY POWERFUL
THAT NIGHT.
I WAS INSPIRED.
>> I WANT TO TALK ABOUT YOUR
PRIVATE LIFE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
NO, NOT THAT YOUR HUSBAND USES
VIAGRA OR NOTHING.
VERY CUTE GUY THE.
SWIZZ --
>> BEATZ.
>> SWIZZ BEATZ AND YOU HAVE A
2-YEAR-OLD NAMED EGYPT.
>> HE'S CUTE.
>> AND OBVIOUSLY IT HAS TO
CHANGE YOUR LIFE BUT HAS IT
AFFECTED YOUR MUSIC?
>> YOU KNOW, IT'S CHANGED
EVERYTHING WITHOUT QUESTION AND
I GUESS YOU NEVER KNOW THAT
UNTIL IT REALLY HAPPENS, BUT
IT'S MADE ME SO MUCH BETTER, I
FEEL LIKE.
I'VE BECOME SO MUCH WISER AND SO
MUCH MORE REALLY READY TO STEP
INTO MY WOMANHOOD AND EMPOWERED
AND I THINK THAT'S COME THROUGH
IN THE MUSIC A LOT.
I'VE BEEN READY TO MAKE CHOICES
I DIDN'T KNOW HOW TO MAKE
BEFORE.
>> BECAUSE YOU HAVE A BABY.
>> YOU BECOME THIS LIONESS.
ALL OF A SUDDEN YOU'RE LIKE, NO.
>> DO YOU SING TO HIM.
>> I SING TO HIM ALL NIGHT.
HE'S VERY DEMANDING.
>> WHAT DO YOU SING.
>> A SONG ON MY ALBUM CALLED
"NOT EVEN THE KING."
LIKE A LULLABY AND I SING AN
"OLIV
"OLIVER" SONG.
♪ WHERE IS LOVE
>> THAT'S A PRETTY ONE TOO SO I
SING A COUPLE SONGS.
>> DOES HE SING TO YOU.
>> HE DOES.
WE READ THIS BOOK CALLED "I LOVE
YOU FOREVER."
I MEANT TO TELL MY FRIENDS THAT
GAVE ME THAT BOOK SO I SING THIS
LITTLE SONG WITH THE PART -- THE
SONG AND NOW HE'S SINGING IT TO
ME.
IF I TRY TO SING IT, MOMMY, NO.
LET ME GET MY SHINE ON, PLEASE.
>> NOW, YOU GO ON TOUR NEXT
YEAR.
>> YES.
>> YOU'RE GOING TO TAKE HIM WITH
YOU.
>> YES.
I COULDN'T EVEN BREATHE IF HE
WASN'T WITH ME.
>> BECAUSE WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
THE THINGS THAT CHANGES THAT
YOU'RE DOING BUT IT'S RARE THAT
YOU ACTUALLY COLLABORATED WITH
AS MANY ARTISTS AS YOU HAVE
COLLABORATED WITH ON THIS ALBUM.
JOHN LEGEND, NICKI MINAJ, FRANK
OCEAN, BRUNO MARS.
WHAT DID IT?
WHAT MADE YOU SAY, YOU KNOW
WHAT, I NEED TO DO THIS WITH
THESE FOLKS.
>> YOU KNOW, I THINK IT'S PART
OF LIKE WHAT I WAS SAYING TO
YOU, MISS BARBARA, ABOUT LIKE
BEING EMPOWERED AND BEING REALLY
CAPABLE AND UNAFRAID.
I THINK BEFORE IN MY ARTISTRY I
WOULD FEEL VERY PRIVATE AND LIKE
LET ME JUST HAVE MY MOMENT OR
WORRIED ABOUT COLLABORATING WITH
OTHER PEOPLE AND THIS TIME I
FELT REALLY FREE AND REALLY
EXCITED ABOUT BEING ABLE TO JUST
TRY.
>> LIKE A GROWN-UP.
>> LIKE A GROWN WOMAN.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> WAS THIS MARRIAGE OR THE
BABY --
>> I THINK IT'S A MIXTURE.
I REALLY DO.
HAPPINESS AND FINDING YOUR
SPACE.
>> THE TITLE OF THE CD "GIRL ON
FIRE" IS THIS WHAT IT MEANS?
I READ YOU WERE INSPIRED BY AN
ARTICLE YOU READ ABOUT YOURSELF.
EXPLAIN WHERE IT CAME FROM
REALLY AND THEN HOW YOU THINK
ABOUT THAT NOW.
>> YEAH, "GIRL ON FIRE" IS
DEFINITELY A REPRESENTATION OF
WHAT I STEPPED INTO AND HOW I
FEEL AND WHAT IT REALLY MEANS IS
STEPPING INTO YOUR PASSION AND
BEING UNAFRAID TO BE WHO YOU ARE
AND LIKE STANDING IN THERE NO
MATTER HOW FAR THE JOURNEY IS
LEFT TO GO.
STANDING WHERE YOU ARE AND BEING
PROUD OF IT AND SO THAT'S WHAT
IT MEANS AND A BEAUTIFUL WOMAN,
A BEAUTIFUL WRITER, AMBER, WROTE
THIS BEAUTIFUL WORD THAT SAID
SHE'S LIKE A GIRL ON FIRE AND
WHEN I READ THAT I WAS LIKE, I'M
WRITING THAT SONG.
I'M WRITING THAT SONG.
THAT'S HOW IT HAPPENED.
>> ONE THING ABOUT BEING
UNAFRAID A LOT ARE AFRAID TO CUT
THEIR HAIR NOW THIS HAIRSTYLE,
IT LOOKS GORGEOUS ON YOU,
STUNNING.
>> THANK YOU.
>> IT'S CALLED THE BIG CHOP.
NOW, YOU CHOP -- WE'RE USED TO
BRAIDS.
THE CORNROWS, LONG HAIR AND
YOU'VE CUT IT ALL OFF AND
SYMBOLIC OF JUST BEING FREE.
>> YEAH, YOU KNOW, THE SONG ON
THE ALBUM CALLED "NEW DAY" AND
THE SONG DROPPED IN THE SUMMER
AND, YOU KNOW, I'VE BEEN TALKING
ABOUT CUTTING MY HAIR FOR AWHILE
AND IT FELT LIKE I WAS REALLY
READY FOR IT AND READY TO LET GO
OF ANY OTHER ENERGY THAT I'D
CARRIED THROUGHOUT MY LIFE AND
JUST REALLY LIKE BEGIN FRESH AND
SO I REALLY, WHEW, I WASN'T
SCARED.
ALL FELL ON THE FLOOR AND I WAS
LIKE, HMM!
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> NOW, WHAT DOES SWIZZ THINK?
>> THE HILARIOUS PART, HE'S
LIKE, YOU SHOULD CUT IT.
I DIDN'T TELL HIM.
HE WAS AWAY AND PUT IT ALL BACK
JUST LIKE IN THIS BRUSH-BACK
THING.
HE WAS KIND OF LIKE DOING HIS
THING AND I'M LIKE WAITING FOR
HIM TO NOTICE LIKE --
[ LAUGHTER ]
LIKE LOOK!
SO HE'S LIKE, WHAT.
YOU DID IT.
HE WAS REALLY, REALLY EXCITED.
YOU DIDN'T TELL ME.
YOU DIDN'T SHOW ME.
IT'S A SURPRISE.
>> I HAVE TO STOP YOU BASS I
HAVE TO TELL THE PEOPLE ALICIA
WILL SING HER LATEST TUNE WHEN
WE COME BACK AND WE'LL BE RIGHT
BACK.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
I LOVE HOW CLEAN MY MOUTH IS
AFTER A DENTAL CLEANING...
I JUST WISH
I COULD KEEP IT THIS WAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
NOW YOU CAN.
WITH THE CREST PRO-HEALTH
CLINICAL LINE.
USED TOGETHER,
THEY HELP KEEP YOUR TEETH
97% AS CLEAN
AS A DENTAL CLEANING.
THE TOOTHPASTE
ACTUALLY REDUCES PLAQUE.
AND THE RINSE REACHES ALL AREAS
AND IS CLINICALLY PROVEN TO
HELP PREVENT PLAQUE REGROWTH.
CREST PRO-HEALTH CLINICAL LINE.
TOGETHER, THEY HELP KEEP
YOUR TEETH
97% AS CLEAN
AS A DENTAL CLEANING.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
A BODY AT REST
TENDS TO STAY AT REST...
WHILE A BODY IN MOTION
TENDS TO STAY IN MOTION.
STAYING ACTIVE CAN ACTUALLY
EASE ARTHRITIS SYMPTOMS.
BUT IF YOU HAVE ARTHRITIS,
STAYING ACTIVE
CAN BE DIFFICULT.
PRESCRIPTION CELEBREX
CAN HELP RELIEVE ARTHRITIS PAIN
SO YOUR BODY
CAN STAY IN MOTION.
BECAUSE JUST ONE
200MG CELEBREX A DAY
CAN PROVIDE 24 HOUR RELIEF
FOR MANY WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND INFLAMMATION.
PLUS, IN CLINICAL STUDIES,
CELEBREX IS PROVEN TO IMPROVE
DAILY PHYSICAL FUNCTION
SO MOVING IS EASIER.
CELEBREX CAN BE TAKEN WITH
OR WITHOUT FOOD.
AND IT'S NOT A NARCOTIC.
YOU AND YOUR DOCTOR
SHOULD BALANCE THE BENEFITS
WITH THE RISKS.
ALL PRESCRIPTION NSAIDS,
LIKE CELEBREX, IBUPROFEN,
NAPROXEN, AND MELOXICAM
HAVE THE SAME
CARDIOVASCULAR WARNING.
THEY ALL MAY INCREASE
THE CHANCE
OF HEART ATTACK OR STROKE,
WHICH CAN LEAD TO DEATH.
THIS CHANCE INCREASES
IF YOU HAVE HEART DISEASE
OR RISK FACTORS
SUCH AS HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE
OR WHEN NSAIDS ARE TAKEN
FOR LONG PERIODS.
NSAIDS, INCLUDING CELEBREX,
INCREASE THE CHANCE OF SERIOUS
SKIN OR ALLERGIC REACTIONS
OR STOMACH AND INTESTINE
PROBLEMS,
SUCH AS BLEEDING AND ULCERS,
WHICH CAN OCCUR WITHOUT WARNING
AND MAY CAUSE DEATH.
PATIENTS ALSO TAKING ASPIRIN
AND THE ELDERLY
ARE AT INCREASED RISK FOR
STOMACH BLEEDING AND ULCERS.
DO NOT TAKE CELEBREX IF YOU'VE
HAD AN ASTHMA ATTACK, HIVES,
OR OTHER ALLERGIES TO ASPIRIN,
NSAIDS OR SULFONAMIDES.
GET HELP RIGHT AWAY IF YOU HAVE
SWELLING OF THE FACE OR THROAT,
OR TROUBLE BREATHING.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
YOUR MEDICAL HISTORY
AND FIND AN ARTHRITIS TREATMENT
FOR YOU.
VISIT CELEBREX.COM AND ASK
YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT CELEBREX.
FOR A BODY IN MOTION.
[ Female Announcer ]
HOLIDAY COOKIES ARE A BIG JOB.
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE
JUST RIGHT.
PERFECTION IS IN THE DETAILS.
♪
GET TO HOLIDAY FUN FASTER
WITH PILLSBURY COOKIE DOUGH.
IT'S SO GREAT
TO SEE YOU.
YOU, TOO!
OH, CLOUDY GLASSES.
YOU DIDN'T
HAVE TO COME OVER!
ACTUALLY, HONEY,
I THINK I DID...
OH? YOU DID?
WHOA, LADIES, EASY.
HI.
CASCADE KITCHEN COUNSELOR.
WE CAN HELP AVOID THIS
WITH CASCADE COMPLETE PACS.
SEE, OVER TIME,
CASCADE COMPLETE PACS
FIGHT FILM BUILDUP TWO TIMES
BETTER THAN FINISH QUANTUM.
TO HELP LEAVE GLASSES SPARKLING
SHINY!
TOO BAD IT DOESN'T WORK
ON WINDOWS.
OKAY, I'M OUTTA HERE.
CASCADE. THE CLEAR CHOICE.
BUT SINCE I'VE BEEN ON ALLI,
AM I ON THIS ONE?
NOPE.
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
I AM ON THIS ONE.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR EVERY 2 POUNDS YOU LOSE
THROUGH DIET AND EXERCISE
ALLI CAN HELP YOU LOSE
ONE MORE
BY BLOCKING SOME OF THE FAT
YOU EAT.
SIMPLE. EFFECTIVE.
BELT-FRIENDLY.
LET'S FIGHT FAT WITH ALLI.
HAVE A HEALTHIER HOLIDAY
AT LETSFIGHTHOLIDAYFAT.COM.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>>> HERE TO PERFORM "BRAND NEW
ME" FROM HER INCREDIBLE CD "GIRL
ON FIRE," WELCOME BACK ALICIA
KEYS.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪
♪ IT'S BEEN A WHILE
I'M NOT WHO I WAS BEFORE ♪
♪ YOU LOOK SURPRISED
YOUR WORDS DON'T BURN ME
ANYMORE ♪
♪ BEEN MEANING TO TELL YOU
BUT I GUESS IT'S CLEAR TO SEE ♪
♪ DON'T BE MAD
IT'S JUST THE BRAND NEW KIND OF
ME ♪
♪ CAN'T BE MAD
I FOUND A BRAND NEW KIND OF
FREE ♪
♪ CAREFUL WITH YOUR EGO
HE'S THE ONE THAT WE SHOULD
BLAME ♪
♪ HAD TO GRAB MY HEART BACK
GOD KNOWS SOMETHING HAD TO
CHANGE ♪
♪ I THOUGHT THAT YOU'D BE HAPPY
I FOUND THE ONE THING I NEED ♪
♪ WHY YOU MAD IT'S JUST THE
BRAND NEW KIND OF ME ♪
♪ OH IT TOOK A LONG LONG ROAD TO
GET HERE ♪
♪ IT TOOK A "BRAVE" GIRL TO
TRY ♪
♪ IT TOOK ONE TOO MANY EXCUSES
ONE TOO MANY LIES ♪
♪ DON'T BE SURPRISED
DON'T BE SURPRISED ♪
♪ IF I TALK A LITTLE LOUDER
IF I SPEAK UP WHEN YOU'RE
WRONG ♪
♪ IF I WALK A LITTLE TALLER
I'VE BEEN ON TO YOU TOO LONG ♪
♪ IF YOU NOTICED THAT I'M
DIFFERENT DON'T TAKE IT
PERSONALLY ♪
♪ DON'T BE MAD IT'S JUST THE
BRAND NEW KIND OF ME ♪
♪ IT CAN'T BE BAD
I FOUND A BRAND NEW KIND OF
FREE ♪
♪ OH IT TOOK A LONG LONG ROAD TO
GET HERE ♪
♪ IT TOOK A BRAVE BRAVE GIRL TO
TRY ♪
♪ I'VE TAKEN ONE TOO MANY
EXCUSES ONE TOO MANY LIES ♪
♪ DON'T BE SURPRISED
OH SEE YOU LOOK SURPRISED ♪
♪ HEY IF YOU WERE A FRIEND YOU'D
WANT TO GET TO KNOW ME AGAIN ♪
♪ IF YOU WERE WORTH A WHILE
YOU'D BE HAPPY TO SEE ME SMILE ♪
♪ I'M NOT EXPECTING SORRY
I'M TOO BUSY FINDING MYSELF ♪
♪ I GOT THIS
I FOUND ME
I FOUND ME YEAH ♪
♪ I DON'T NEED YOUR OPINION
I'M NOT WAITING FOR YOUR OKAY ♪
♪ I'LL NEVER BE PERFECT
BUT AT LEAST NOW I'M BRAVE ♪
♪ NOW MY HEART IS OPEN
AND I CAN FINALLY BREATHE ♪
♪ DON'T BE MAD IT'S JUST THE
BRAND NEW KIND OF FREE ♪
♪ THAT AIN'T BAD I FOUND A BRAND
NEW KIND OF ME ♪
♪ DON'T BE MAD
IT'S JUST A BRAND NEW TIME FOR
ME YEAH ♪
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> THANK YOU, GUYS.
>> WHOO!
THANK YOU TO ALICIA KEYS.
WE LOVE YOU.
MEMBERS OF THE AUDIENCE ARE
GOING HOME WITH A COPY OF
ALICIA'S CD.
HAVE A GREAT DAY, EVERYONE, AND
TAKE A LITTLE TIME TO ENJOY "THE
VIEW."
>> Announcer: LOVE IS IN THE
AIR.
THE SEASON PREMIERE OF "THE
BACHELOR" IS MONDAY, JANUARY
8th, 7:
>>> BREAKING NEWS IN
CONNECTICUT, A NEW THREAT HAS
FORCED A SCHOOL CLOSURE.
>>> SPORTING GOODS STORE SET
TO OPEN IN LOS GATOS.
NEIGHBOR ARE AFRAID OF WHAT IT
MIGHT SELL.
>> SINKHOLE WHAóñó
CAPTIONED BY
CLOSED CAPTIONING SERVICES, INC.
>>> GOOD MORNING I'M ERIC
THOMAS IN FOR CHERYL JENNINGS.
>>> AND I'M KRISTEN SZE
BREAKING NEWS FROM NEWTOWN
CONNECTICUT.
ANOTHER SCHOOL HAS BEEN
CLOSED.
CLASSES ARE CANCELLED TODAY
AFTER AN UNSPECIFIED THREAT.
WHEN PARENTS ARRIVE TO DROP
OFF KIDS THEY PHONE THE