MINE.
DETECTIVE KATE BECKETT.
BECKETT.
NIKKI HEAT?
THE CHARACTER
HE'S BASING ON YOU.
AND THANKS TO MY FRIENDSHIP
WITH THE MAYOR,
I GET TO BE ON HER CASE.
I WOULD BE HAPPY
TO LET YOU SPANK ME.
AND TOGETHER...
WE SOLVE CRIMES.
WE MAKE A PRETTY GOOD TEAM,
YOU KNOW?
LIKE STARSKY AND HUTCH,
TURNER AND HOOCH.
YOU DO REMIND ME
A LITTLE OF HOOCH.
(Junior Senior)
♪ CAN I GET GET GET
♪ TTER, BABY? W
YOU BETTER BETTER, BABY? ♪
♪ CAN I GET GET GET
TO KNOW KNOW KNOW KNOW ♪
♪ YOU BETTER BETTER, BABY?
(man) SEXY, SEXY.
LADIES, I LOVE IT.
I LOVE IT. I LOVE IT.
SEXY SEXY IS NOT A CRIME.
(woman) WHAT'S SO SPECIAL ABOUT
WORLD-FAMOUS MYSTERY NOVELIST
RICHARD CASTLE?
HE'S RICH, HE'S HANDSOME
AND HE'S BASING
HIS NEXT BEST SELLER ON YOU.
TELL ME, DETECTIVE BECKETT,
WHAT'S IT LIKE
BEING THE INSPIRATION FOR
THRILL MASTER RICHARD CASTLE'S
NEW CHARACTER NIKKI HEAT?
ON BEHALF OF THE NYPD,
IT HAS BEEN A PLEASURE
TO OFFER MR. CASTLE
INSIGHT INTO THE PROFESSION.
GIVEN ALL HIS BEST SELLERS,
IT'S OBVIOUS MR. CASTLE
HAS TREMENDOUS INSIGHT
INTO THE CRIMINAL MIND.
I'M TOLD IN MANY OCCASIONS,
HIS PARTICIPATION
WAS ESSENTIAL TO SOLVING
YOUR TOUGHEST CASES.
REALLY?
YOU WERE TOLD THAT?
BY WHO?
BY CASTLE.
(man) TRY UNBUTTONING HIS SHIRT.
JUST--JUST THE FIRST ONE.
RIGHT THERE. YEAH.
COULD YOU EXCUSE ME
FOR A MOMENT?
(man) LOVE IT. I LOVE IT.
SIR, COULD I TALK TO YOU
IN PRIVATE
FOR A MOMENT, PLEASE?
BECKETT, I HAVE A COUPLE--
NOW.
WE HAD A DEAL, BECKETT.
THE DEAL IS OFF.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM?
NOT ONLY DOES HE HAVE
THE BACHELOR-PARTY COP TWINS
OUT THERE
USING HIM AS A STRIPPER POLE
WHILE I MAKE NICEY-NICE
WITH THE PRESS,
BUT DO YOU KNOW WHAT HE SAID?
NO.
HE SAID THAT HE HAS BEEN
INSTRUMENTAL
IN HELPING US SOLVE CRIMES.
WELL, HASN'T HE?
THAT'S NOT THE POINT.
DO YOU KNOW HOW HARD IT IS
FOR NYPD TO GET GOOD PRESS?
I MEAN, IN A MAGAZINE
THAT PEOPLE ACTUALLY READ.
THIS ARTICLE IS
VERY IMPORTANT TO THE MAYOR.
THEREFORE, WE ARE
GOING TO COOPERATE.
DO I MAKE MYSELF CLEAR?
OKAY. FINE.
IT WAS NICE
TO MEET YOU.
WE SHOULD HAVE
PHOTO SHOOTS HERE MORE OFTEN.
HEY, BECKETT, HOW COME YOU
DON'T WEAR A UNIFORM LIKE THAT?
BECAUSE I DON'T WANT
TO GET PAID IN SINGLES.
HEY.
OH, HEY. UH,
DON'T WE HAVE THAT THING?
NO.
YEAH, YOU KNOW,
THAT THING WITH THE GUY?
OH, YEAH.
THE THING WITH THE GUY.
YEAH, EXCUSE US.
I JUST WANTED YOU TO KNOW,
I HAD NOTHING TO DO WITH THIS.
I MEAN, IT WAS THE MAGAZINE.
AND--AND, WELL, THE MAYOR
THOUGHT IT WOULD BE GOOD PRESS.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO
EXPLAIN YOURSELF?
REALLY. SEE?
I DON'T CARE ANYMORE.
NOW IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME, I HAVE
AN INTERVIEW TO GET BACK TO.
WHAT DID I DO
THAT WAS SO WRONG?
THE ONE THING
I ASKED YOU NOT TO DO.
OKAY.
SO YOU ASKED ME NOT TO
LOOK INTO YOUR MOTHER'S MURDER,
BUT LOOK AT WHAT I FOUND.
IT DOESN'T MATTER
WHAT YOU FOUND.
I PUT THAT ALL BEHIND ME
A LONG TIME AGO.
WE CAN GET BACK
TO THE INTERVIEW NOW.
NO, GONNA HAVE TO RESCHEDULE.
WE JUST CAUGHT A BODY.
SO SORRY TO STEP OUT
ON YOU, AMY.
OOH, ARE YOU KIDDING?
IT'S PERFECT.
A CHANCE TO SEE CASTLE
IN ACTION.
OUR READERS WILL LOVE IT.
WELL, WE WOULDN'T WANT TO
DISAPPOINT YOUR READERS,
NOW WOULD WE, DETECTIVE?
(siren wailing)
(police radio chatter)
HEY. CAN WE TALK
ABOUT THIS, PLEASE?
THERE'S NOTHING
TO TALK ABOUT.
WELL, JUST AT LEAST
LET ME KNOW
WHAT I CAN DO
TO MAKE IT UP TO YOU.
YOU COULD LEAVE ME ALONE.
YES. WELL, I TRIED THAT,
AND IT DIDN'T WORK.
HEY, I COULD BUY YOU
A PONY.
FOCUS, CASTLE.
CRIME SCENE, OKAY?
IT'S RAINING MEN.
CASTLE,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
DON'T WORRY.
WE'RE STILL MAD AT HIM.
GUY IN A TREE,
MOM AND DAD BICKERING--
SEEMS LIKE OLD TIMES.
MM-HMM.
HOW'S IT GOING UP THERE?
I GOT TREE BRANCHES
POKING MY BOOBS
AND SPOTLIGHTS
SHINING UP MY BOOTY.
COULD BE WORSE.
YOU COULD BE WEARING A SKIRT.
WHEN I COME DOWN,
I'M-A SMACK YOU.
I'LL BE LOOKING FORWARD
TO THAT.
HERE.
VIC'S A WHITE MALE,
LATE 30s.
JUDGING FROM
THE CRACKED BRANCHES,
I'M GUESSING HE DID A SUPERMAN
OFF THE TOP OF THAT BUILDING.
(Esposito) VIC'S NAME
IS JOHN ALLEN.
I.D. HAS HIM
ON THE UPPER WEST SIDE.
BUSINESS CARD HAS HIM
IN INSURANCE.
MM.
IS IT A SU
IS IT A SUICIDE?
(Castle and Beckett)
IT'S NOT A SUICIDE.
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
UM, THE BUILDING
IS TOO SHORT.
HE'D WANT TO KILL HIMSELF,
NOT CRIPPLE HIMSELF.
WELL, IF YOU WANT TO DIE,
YOU'RE GONNA AIM FOR CONCRETE,
NOT A TREE.
JUDGING FROM
THE ANGLE OF DESCENT,
I'D SAY THAT GUY WAS THROWN
OFF THE BUILDING.
SINCE IT CLEARLY WASN'T
A SUICIDE, HOW DID HE DIE?
THERE ARE SIGNS
OF STRANGULATION.
IT LOOKS LIKE
HIS WINDPIPE WAS CRUSHED.
ANY LIGATURE MARKS?
NOPE.
"LIGATURE" REFERS TO
ANYTHING THAT TIES OR BINDS,
LIKE A ROPE OR A BELT.
LACK OF ANY MARKS SUGGESTS
HE WAS STRANGLED BY HAND.
WOW. YOU REALL NO W
NO WONDER THEY LIKE
HAVING YOU AROUND.
YOU KNOW WHAT? HE'S SUCH
AN INCREDIBLE RESOURCE,
IT SEEMS LIKE A SHAME TO WASTE
HIS TALENTS HERE IN THE FIELD.
WOULD YOU MIND GOING BACK
TO THE MORGUE WITH DR. PARISH
TO SEE WHAT ELSE WE CAN
FIND OUT ABOUT THE VIC?
DON'T YOU THINK
I'D BE OF MORE USE
HERE AT THE CRIME SCENE?
OH, NO. WE'RE JUST GONNA
KNOCK ON DOORS
AND SEE WHAT ELSE
WE CAN STIR UP.
YOU KNOW,
BORING POLICE STUFF.
FINE. BUT I WAS SERIOUS
ABOUT THE PONY.
COME ON, I'LL SHOW YOU
THE, UH, MORGUE... MOBILE.
ANYTHING IN THE WALLET?
NOPE. DRY CLEANING TICKET,
I.D., TWO CREDIT CARDS.
CASH WAS MISSING, THOUGH.
THAT'S A LONG WAY TO GO
FOR A ROBBERY.
(siren whoops)
(police radio chatter)
YOU MEAN WE HAVE TO RIDE
WITH THE BODY?
YOU CAN TAKE MY SEAT
UP FRONT.
YOU SURE?
MM-HMM. I'M USED
TO HANGING OUT WITH STIFFS.
(chuckles)
(police radio chatter)
HI.
UNH-UNH. YOU DO NOT
GET TO SAY HI TO ME.
I'M JUST DOING MY GIRL
A FAVOR.
OH, YOU, TOO, HUH?
WELL, WHAT DID YOU EXPECT?
BECKETT SPENT THE FIRST
THREE YEARS OF BEING A COP
TRYING TO SOLVE
HER MOTHER'S MURDER.
IT TOOK EVERYTHING THAT SHE HAD
TO PUT IT BEHIND HER.
YOU COULDN'T RESPECT THAT?
WHAT WAS I SUPPOSED TO DO,
NOT TELL HER WHAT I'D FOUND?
WHAT YOU FOUND?
OH, SHE DIDN'T TELL YOU,
DID SHE?
THREE PEOPLE WERE KILLED
THE SAME WAY HER MOTHER WAS
RIGHT ABOUT THE SAME TIME.
ONE OF 'EM WAS
A FORMER LAW STUDENT OF HERS.
ANOTHER ONE,
A DOCUMENTS CLERK.
THE THIRD ONE,
A LAWYER FOR A NONPROFIT.
WAIT, THE M.E. AT THE TIME
DIDN'T MAKE THE CONNECTION?
IF HE DID,
HE BURIED IT.
DID YOU TALK TO HIM?
HE DIED FOUR YEARS AGO.
SO YOU SEE
WHY I HAD TO TELL HER.
WHAT DID SHE SAY?
THAT WE WERE DONE.
AND THEN SHE JUST WALKED--
(metal crunches)
(tires squeal)
(man) COME ON! GO! GO! GO!
(metal clatters)
DON'T MOVE. DON'T MOVE.
WHOA!
(man) GET THE BODY!
(man grunts)
GO!
DON'T MOVE!
(man) COME ON, MOVE!
COME ON!
(engine revs)
(tires squeal)
IS IT JUST ME, OR WAS THAT
REALLY, REALLY WEIRD?
♪
Captioned by
Closed Captioning Services, Inc.
A deep, throbbing,
persistent ache.
My doctor diagnosed it
as fibromyalgia,
thought to be the
result of overactive nerves
that cause chronic
widespread pain.
Lyrica is believed
to calm these nerves.
I learned Lyrica can provide
significant relief
from fibromyalgia pain.
And for some people,
it can work in as early as
the first week of treatment.
So now I can do more of
the things that I enjoy.
Lyrica is not for everyone.
Lyrica may cause serious
allergic reactions
or suicidal thoughts or actions.
Tell your doctor right away
if you have these,
new or worsening depression,
or unusual changes in mood
or behavior,
or any swelling on,
or changes in eyesight,
including blurry vision
or muscle pain with fever
or tired feeling.
Common side effects
are dizziness, sleepiness,
weight gain, and swelling of
hands, legs and feet.
Don't drink alcohol
while taking Lyrica.
Don't drive or use machinery
until you know
how Lyrica affects you.
With less pain,
I'm feeling better
now that I've found Lyrica.
Ask your doctor
if Lyrica is right
for your fibromyalgia pain.
YOU SPEND ALL DAY COOKING IT.
SO WHY SPEND EVEN A MOMENT
CONSIDERING ANY BROTH
BUT SWANSON?
THE BROTH COOKS TRUST MOST
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
IN STUFFING AND MORE,
THE SECRET IS SWANSON.
ELL?
HE'LL LIVE.
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
WHAT, NO BRAIN DAMAGE?
IF HE HAS SOME, IT HAPPENED
WAY BEFORE TONIGHT,
AND IT WAS PROBABLY
SELF-INFLICTED.
AHH. GOOD TIMES.
HOW'S LOIS LANE?
WHO, REPORTER CHICK?
WE TOOK HER STATEMENT
AND WE SENT HER HOME.
WE GOT AN A.P.B. ON THE SEDAN,
C.S.U.s ARE COMBING THE ROOFTOP,
AND WE GOT UNIs LOOKING FOR
SURVEILLANCE FOOTAGE
OF THE CRASH SITE.
YOU KNOW WHAT I DON'T GET
IS WHO WOULD STEAL
A DEAD BODY?
OH, PLENTY OF PEOPLE--
UH, ORGAN HARVESTERS,
CADAVERLESS MED STUDENTS,
SATANISTS,
MAD SCIENTISTS LOOKING TO
CREATE THEIR OWN MONSTER.
OR THE GUYS WHO KILLED HIM
MIGHT HAVE LEFT
SOME EVIDENCE BEHIND.
BORING.
HOW ABOUT A SPY
THAT THE ENEMY WED
A TOP-SECRET MICROCHIP
THAT THE ENEMY FORCES
MURDER HIM OVER
BEFORE THE C.I.A.
CAN GET AHOLD OF HIM?
AS MUCH AS WE ALL APPRECIATE
YOUR INSIGHTFUL
AND INCREDIBLY BELIEVABLE
THEORIES,
MISS "COSMO" IS GONE,
SO I BELIEVE
YOU CAN GO HOME NOW.
HOME? NO. NO, NO, NO.
CASE JUST GOT GOOD.
AND--AND I'M--
I'M A WITNESS.
ALL RIGHT, I'LL LET YOU WORK
THIS ONE CASE WITH ME
IF YOU PROMISE TO
LEAVE ME ALONE WHEN IT'S OVER
AND NOT TO WEASEL YOUR WAY
BACK IN.
DEAL.
BUT FAIR WARNING,
DETECTIVE.
I WILL MAKE YOU
CHANGE YOUR MIND.
I WON'T.
YOU WILL.
(Castle) SO WHAT'S
THE NEXT STEP, VICTIM'S FAMILY?
HUH. I DIDN'T THINK
SHE'D TAKE HIM BACK.
(knock on door)
MRS. ALLEN?
YES.
IT'S ABOUT YOUR HUSBAND.
HE WAS JUST RIGHT HERE
JUST A COUPLE OF HOURS AGO,
AND NOW HE'S DEAD. I...
DO YOU KNOW OF ANY REASON WHY
HE'D BE IN THAT PART OF TOWN?
NO.
HIS OFFICE IS, UH,
IN MIDTOWN.
IT'S NOWHERE NEAR NINTH.
WHAT TIME DID HE LEAVE
THE APARTMENT?
AROUND 6:00.
HE HAD JUST GOTTEN BACK
FROM HIS TRIP
AND, UH, HE SAID HE NEEDED
TO CATCH UP ON SOME PAPERWORK.
HE SAID HE'D ONLY BE GONE
FOR A COUPLE OF HOURS.
YOU SAID A TRIP?
HE WAS IN ALBUQUERQUE
ON A TRAINING SEMINAR.
IT WAS JUST TWO NIGHTS.
DID YOU NOTICE ANYTHING
UNUSUAL RECENTLY,
ANY STRANGE BEHAVIOR?
WELL, HE--
HE HAD TO WORK LATE
A LITTLE MORE OFTEN
THAN USUAL.
BUT I MEAN, IN THIS ECONOMY,
WHO DOESN'T?
HE HAD TO LAY OFF
HALF HIS DEPARTMENT LAST YEAR.
AND YOU'RE SURE
HE WAS WORKING LATE?
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING,
THAT HE WAS CHEATING?
EVERY NIGHT, HE WOULD
WALK THROUGH THAT DOOR,
AND THE KIDS WOULD JUST
RACE INTO HIS ARMS, OKAY?
AND NOW HE'S GONE.
SO DON'T ASK ME IF HE WAS
REALLY WORKING LATE.
TELL ME WHY HE WAS KILLED.
HE DIDN'T MEAN TO IMPLY--
WHAT ABOUT PHONE CALLS,
MAYBE LATE AT NIGHT?
CASTLE.
YEAH. YEAH. UM...
(sniffles) ONE OF THE GUYS
THAT JOHN FIRED--
MAX HAVERSTOCK.
HE WOULD CALL HIM UP
LATE AT NIGHT,
AND HE WOULD YELL AT HIM,
ALL SORTS OF THINGS.
I GUESS HE WAS HURTING,
HE NEEDED MONEY.
AND I-I TOLD JOHN THAT
HE SHOULD JUST HANG UP ON HIM.
AND JOHN SAID NO, HE--
HE COULDN'T DO THAT.
DID HE EVER GIVE HIM MONEY?
MY HUSBAND DIDN'T BELIEVE
IN HANDOUTS.
HE BELIEVED THAT A MAN
SHOULD MAKE HIS WAY.
WHERE IS HE?
I'D LIKE TO SAY GOOD-BYE.
ABOUT THAT. UM...
THAT WAS AWKWARD.
(scoffs) IT JUST--
IT DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE.
THE GUY'S GOT A STABLE,
MIDDLE-CLASS LIFE--
GOOD JOB, GOOD FAMILY.
MAYBE HIS FRIEND MAX
WAS JEALOUS.
(keypad beeps, telephone rings)
YEAH, MAYBE ENOUGH TO KILL HIM,
BUT TO STEAL HIS BODY?
HEY, ESPOSITO. I NEED YOU
TO LOOK UP A FRIEND OF THE VIC.
MAX HAVERSTOCK.
(elevator bell dings)
YEAH.
OKAY, FIND HIM
AND, UH, BRING HIM IN.
(keys jangle)
DAD. THANK GOD YOU'RE HOME.
ARE YOU OKAY?
YEAH, I'M FINE. WHY?
FINE? MASKED GUNMEN,
BODY SNATCHERS?
I TEXTED YOU
LIKE A THOUSAND TIMES.
OH, I'M SORRY.
MY PHONE MUST'VE BEEN OFF.
HOW--HOW DID YOU KNOW?
BECKETT CALLED.
REALLY?
SHE JUST WANTED TO LET US KNOW
YOU WERE ALL RIGHT.
MM-HMM.
SO HAS SHE FORGIVEN YOU?
UH, NOT EXACTLY, MOTHER.
BUT I'M WORKING ON IT.
SHE HAS AGREED
TO LET ME HELP ON THE CASE.
WELL, THAT'S A START,
I SUPPOSE.
IT IS MORE THAN A START.
IT IS AN OPPORTUNITY.
EEN US,BUILT A WALL
BETWEEN US,
BUT I AM GOING TO...
BUILD A DOOR IN THAT WALL,
OR PUT UP A LADDER
OR DIG A HOLE.
(keypad beeping)
YOU HAVE A STRATEGY?
BE MY USUAL, CHARMING SELF.
(beeping continues)
UH-HUH.
WHAT ABOUT PLAN "B"?
SO WAS IT AWFUL?
WERE YOU SCARED?
ME, SCARED? NO WAY.
COME ON.
NOW EXCUSE ME
WHILE I CHANGE MY SHORTS.
DAD.
NO, I WAS SCARED. BUT ALL THEY
WERE AFTER WAS THE BODY.
WHY?
WHY INDEED.
(beeping continues)
"DAD, WHERE ARE YOU?
DAD, ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
"DAD, CALL US RIGHT AWAY.
DAD, CAN I GO SEE 'FAME'
WITH OWEN ON FRIDAY?"
YOUR CONCERN IS TOUCHING.
OKAY, THAT ONE WAS AFTER
I KNEW YOU WERE ALL RIGHT.
YEAH, BUT I THOUGHT WE WERE
GONNA GO SEE THAT TOGETHER.
WE WERE, AND WE STILL CAN.
BUT HE INVITED ME TO GO
SEE IT WITH HIM NEXT FRIDAY.
YOU'D RATHER GO WITH
YOUR BOYFRIEND THAN YOUR DAD?
WHAT IS WRONG WITH YOU?
IF YOU REALLY WANT ME
TO GO WITH YOU, I WILL.
NO, NO. YOU TELL OWEN
HE HAS WON THIS ROUND.
BUTI GOT DIBS
ON "A CHRISTMAS CAROL."
THANKS, DAD.
AND I'M GLAD YOU WEREN'T KILLED
BY BODY SNATCHERS.
ME, TOO.
OH, THEY REMADE "FAME"
AND "A CHRISTMAS CAROL."
HAS HOLLYWOOD TOTALLY
RUN OUT OF IDEAS?
WELL, THEY JUST OPTIONED, UH,
"ASTEROIDS" THE VIDEO GAME..
BUT RYAN RD HE'S GOOD.
(chuckTHE WEE TRIANGLE, AND HE')
ARE YOU SURE
THIS IS THE GUY?
MAXWELL HAVERSTOCK.
AND HE CONFIRMED
HE KNEW THE VIC.
THIS GUY COULDN'T THROW
A WET SPONGE OFF THE ROOF
LET ALONE A BODY.
(Beckett) MR. HAVERSTOCK.
YES.
DO YOU KNOW
WHY YOU'RE HERE?
NO. UH, THEY JUST TOLD ME
I NEEDED TO COME IN.
IT'S ABOUT JOHN ALLEN.
HE WAS MURDERED LAST NIGHT.
OH, THAT'S TERRIBLE.
YOU AND HE WERE FRIENDS?
UH, WE HAD
ADJOINING CUBICLES.
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
YOU SAW HIM?
OH, UH, NOT SINCE "D" DAY.
THAT'S, UH, THAT'S WHAT
WE CALLED IT.
YOU KNOW, "D" FOR DOWNSIZING.
(chuckles)
YOU WERE LET GO?
YEAH.
I BET THAT MADE YOU
WE WORKED THERE TOGETHER.RE TOG,
YOU KNOW, YOU'D THINK
THAT WOULD MEAN SOMETHING.
YOU'D THINK THAT LOYALTY
WOULD BE WORTH SOMETHING.
YOU KNOW WHAT IT'S WORTH?
A KICK IN THE TEETH!
DID YOU EVER CALL
AND TELL JOHN THAT?
OH, YEAH, ALL THE TIME.
YEAH, I TOLD HIMN'T DESERVET
WE DIDN'T DESERVE
TO BE TREATED LIKE THAT.PROM
BUT I PROMISED HIM, ONE DAY,
THE WORM WOULD TURN,
'CAUSE KARMA'S
A NASTY LITTLE BITCH.
IS THAT WHY YOU KILLED HIM?
WHO?
JOHN.
WHY WOULD I WANT
TO KILL JOHN?
FOR FIRING YOU.
HE DIDN'T FIRE ME. WE WERE
LET GO TOGETHER ON "D" DAY.
UH, FORTUNATELY, I WAS ABLE
TO FIND ANOTHER JOB.
HE DIDN'T HAVE A JOB?
I GUESS HE, UH, DOESN'T
HAVE TO LOOK FOR ONE ANYMORE.
(chuckles)
HEY, YO, BECKETT.
STORY CHECKS.
JOHN ALLEN WAS LAID OFF
EIGHT MONTHS AGO
WHEN THE A.I.G. CRISIS HIT.
WHAT ABOUT ALBUQUERQUE?
NO RECORD OF A JOHN ALLEN
COMING BACK FROM ANY FLIGHT
IN THE TRI-STATE AREA.
WELL, IT MAKES YOU WONDER WHAT
ELSE HE LIED TO HIS WIFE ABOUT.
(cell phone rings and beeps)
AND HOW HE PAID
ALL OF HIS BILLS. BECKETT.
ALL RIGHT. UH, THANK YOU.
(beep)
THEY FOUND HIS BODY...
AGAIN.
(camera shutter clicking)
(police radio chatter)
WHAT HAPPENED?
SOMEONE...
OPERATED ON HIM.
OPERATED?
THEY CUT HIM OPEN AND TOOK
ALL OF HIS ORGANS OUT.
(Ryan, Castle and Beckett) OH!
(Esposito) OUCH.
(Ryan) WOW.
SOMEBODY HATED HIS GUTS.
(police radio chatter)
♪
THAT'S WHY NEW
Dove Style + Care
Whipped Cream Mousse
NOURISHES AND CONDITIONS
TO HELP KEEP CURLS WELL DEFINED
AND TOUCHABLY SOFT.
NEW Dove Style + Care
Whipped Cream Mousse.
BETTER STYLE
THROUGH BETTER CARE.
Here's a better idea.
Pillsbury Grands!
Flaky Layers Biscuits
In just 15 minutes
the light delicate layers
add a layer of warmth
to your next dinner.
Pillsbury Grands Biscuits
Let the making begin.
[ Female Announcer ]
GO FROM ZERO TO PIZZA
IN JUST 60 SECONDS
WITH TOTINO'S PIZZA ROLLS
AND GRAB A BITE OF
SNACK-DEFYING, SATISFYING...
BECAUSE PIZZA...NEVER...MISSES.
IT'S ON. LET'S ROLL.
O DID THIS
WEREN'T SURGEONS.
THE CUTS ARE SLOPPY--
BOX CUTTERS AND KITCHEN KNIVES.
ANY IDEA WHAT THEY WERE
LOOKING FOR?
I RAN A TOX SCREEN AND FOUND
NOTHING IN THE BLOODSTREAM,
BUT IN THE BODY CAVITY
ITSELF,
THERE WERE TRACE AMOUNTS
OF POWDER COCAINE.
HE WAS THEIR DRUG MULE.
GUESS THEY COULDN'T WAIT
FOR HIM TO PASS THE PACKETS
THE OLD-FASHIONED WAY.
I DON'T BUY IT.
HOW DOES A MIDDLE-AGED
INSURANCE ACTUARY
WITH NO HISTORY
OF SUBSTANCE ABUSE,
NO CRIMINAL RECORD,
BECOME A DRUG MULE?
AND THIS WAS NOT
A BAD GUY.
YOU DON'T JUST FILL OUT
AN AD ON craigslist.
YOU GOTTA--YOU GOTTA
KNOW PEOPLE, BAD PEOPLE.
AS FREAKY AS ALL THIS IS,
LET'S NOT FORGET
IT HAPPENED POSTMORTEM.
THE ACTUAL CAUSE OF DEATH
IS UP HERE.PATTERS
THE ASSAILANT STRANGLED HIM
WITH BOTH HANDS.
THE BRUISING IS
A LITTLE LIGHTER RIGHT THERE.
WHAT WOULD ACCOUNT FOR THAT?
DISLOCATED
OR BROKEN FINGER MAYBE.
MAYBE HE'S FANCY.
SCKING OUT.CKING OUT.
LIKE TEA.
(Esposito) I JUST GOT OFF
WITH HOMELAND SECURITY.
PASSPORT RECORDS INDICATE
THAT JOHN ALLEN
WAS COMING BACK FROM MEXICO,
NOT NEW MEXICO.
NO CRIMINAL HISTORY, HEALTHY,
WHITE, MIDDLE-CLASS--
THEY WOULDN'T HAVE LOOKED
AT HIM TWICE AT CUSTOMS.
THE GUY HAD SKILLS. WHY WOULD
HE DO SOMETHING SO STUPID?
BECAUSE HE HAD TO.
I JUST WENT OVER FINANCIALS
WITH THE WIFE.
HOW BAD?
THEY'VE BEEN LIVING
ON CREDIT CARDS
THE LAST SIX MONTHS.
SHE HAD NO IDEA. SHE THOUGHT
EVERYTHING WAS FINE.
WELL, IF HE WASN'T
GOING TO WORK EVERY DAY,
WHERE WAS HE GOING?
HE WAS APPLYING FOR JOBS.
I FOUND HUNDREDS OF
COVER LETTERS AND RéSUMéS
ON HIS COMPUTER.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND. WHY DIDN'T
THEY JUST SELL THE APARTMENT?
WASN'T WORTH THE MORTGAGE.
MAN, THAT'S HARSH.
LIFE INSURANCE?
(cell phone ringing)
MM. STOPPED MAKING PAYMENTS
FOUR MONTHS AGO.
GUY WAS BASICALLY WORTHLESS,
ALIVE OR DEAD.
(beep)
YEAH, RYAN HERE.
YOU KNOW,
I GET DESPERATION,
I GET NEEDING THE MONEY,
I EVEN GET BEING A DRUG MULE.
WHAT I DON'T GET IS,
YE WHERE DID HE GET THE JOB?
YEAH, THANKS, BILL.
THAT WAS C.S.U.
BECAUSE OUR PERPS
WERE WEARING GLOVES,
THE ONLY PRINTS THEY COULD
GRAB OFF THE CAR BELONG TO
THE OWNER, WHO REPORTED IT
STOLEN LAST NIGHT.
LOOKS LIKE WE'RE NOT GONNA
GRAB A BREAK ON THIS ONE.
WHAT ABOUT THE GLOVE
WE FOUND AT THE SCENE?
DUSTED IT, TOO. NOTHING.
DID YOU DUST INSIDE?
INSIDE?
YEAH, INSIDE THE GLOVE.
YOU WANT ME TO PUT ON
SOME MUSIC?
WHENEVER THEY DO THIS SORT
OF THING ON "CSI,"
THEY ALWAYS DO IT TO MUSIC
IN POORLY LIT ROOMS.
KINDA REMINDS ME OF PORN.
ZIP IT, CASTLE.
EVER CONSIDER
BECOMING A MOHEL?
(chuckles) KEEP TALKING,
AND I'LL PRACTICE ON YOU.
GOT YOU,
YOU SON OF A BITCH.
(beeping)
BOOM. GOT A HIT.
OOH, LUTHER WHITEHEAD.
BUSTED TWICE FOR POSSESSION
WITH INTENT.
ONCE ON CONSPIRACY.
PLED OUT ON ALL THREE.
DID A NICKEL UPSTATE
FOR A GUN CHARGE,
AND IS CURRENTLY ON PAROLE
FOR CONSPIRACY TO DISTRIBUTE.
SOMETHING TELLS ME HIS PAROLE'S
ABOUT TO BE REVOKED.
YOU GOT AN ADDRESS?
(man) ONE, TWO, THREE, FOUR.
♪
(man) WHOA.
HEY...
(grenade crackles, men groan)
(officers all yelling at once)
ON THE GROUND!
GET ON THE GROUND!
HOLD IT RIGHT THERE!
NOBODY MOVE!
(man) HANDS BEHIND YOUR BACK!
(man) HANDS BEHIND
YOUR BACK! HANDS!
COME ON, CREEP.
♪
So I get Claritin Clear...
...for strong, non-drowsy
relief of all my allergies...
...like dust...
...mold...
...pets...
...and pollen.
Looks good.
Thanks.
I Live Claritin Clear.
♪
[ Female Announcer ] MAY YOUR
HOLIDAYS BE MERRY AND BRIGHT.
MERRY PRINGLES.
I DIDN'T WANT TO CHANGE
TOOTHPASTES...
I ALREADY HAD A PRODUCT
THAT MADE MY MOUTH FEEL CLEAN...
THE FIRST THING HE RECOMMENDED
WAS SENSODYNE.
IT HELPS
WITH THE SENSITIVITY ISSUES
AND IT SATISFIES THE NEEDS
THAT I WOULD LOOK FOR
IN A TOOTHPASTE.
AND WITH MY BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CREDIT CARD,
I LOVE 'EM EVEN MORE.
I EARN 1% CASH BACK EVERYWHERE,
EVERY TIME.
2% ON GROCERIES.
3% ON GAS.
AUTOMATICALLY.
NO HOOPS TO JUMP THROUGH.
THAT'S 1% BACK ON...
[ toy robot sounds ]
2% ON PUMPKIN PIE.
AND APPLE.
3% BACK ON 4 TRIPS
TO THE AIRPORT.
IT'S AS EASY AS...
-[ man ] 1...
-[ woman ] 2...
[ woman ] 3.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CARD.
APPLY ONLINE OR AT
A BANK OF AMERICA NEAR YOU.
♪
THAT'S WHY NEW
Dove Style + Care
Whipped Cream Mousse
NOURISHES AND CONDITIONS
TO HELP KEEP CURLS WELL DEFINED
AND TOUCHABLY SOFT.
NEW Dove Style + Care
Whipped Cream Mousse.
BETTER STYLE
THROUGH BETTER CARE.
TOMATO,
OBVIOUSLY.
HAHA. THERE'S MORE
THAN THAT THOUGH,
THERE'S A KICK TO IT.
WAHLALALALALLALA!
SMOOTH, BUT CRISP.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE DRINKING
A FOOD THAT'S A DRINK,
OR A DRINK THAT'S A FOOD,
WOOOOOH!
THAT'S A FOOD, OF LIKE DRINKING
AND DESCRIBE THE INDESCRIBABLE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
THAT'S A FOOD, OF LIKE DRINKING
AND DESCRIBE THE INDESCRIBABLE.
WE WABOUT SOMETHING NO ONE
ASKIWANTS TO TALK ABOUT.ANKLY
IT'S TIME TO GET REAL ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENS IN THE BATHROOM.
STOP ALL THE CUTESY STUFF
AND START TALKING ABOUT
WHAT YOU REALLY WANT
FROM YOUR TOILET PAPER.
IT'S TIME TO TALK ABOUT CLEAN.
FEELING CLEAN IS SO IMPORTANT.
QUILTED NORTHERN SOFT AND STRONG
IS STRONGER THAN THE
LEADING VALUE BRAND,
TO HELP PROTECT
AGAINST BREAKTHROUGH.
FOR MYSELF, FOR MY FAMILY,
IT KEEPS US CLEAN.
I USE QUILTED NORTHERN.
QUILTED NORTHERN
SOFT AND STRONG,
PROTECTION FOR A CONFIDENT
CLEAN OR YOUR MONEY BACK.
LOR, I HAVE THEM
DEAD TO RIGHTS ON WEAPONS
POSSESSION, ASSAULT,
DESECRATION OF A BODY
AND ABOUT
A DOZEN OTHER THINGS
I HAVEN'T EVEN BEGUN
TO THINK ABOUT YET.
WHAT IS MY INCENTIVE
TO CUT A DEAL?
YOU DON'T HAVE THEM
ON THE MURDER.
GIVE ME TIME.
YOU DON'T NEED TIME
BECAUSE THEY DIDN'T DO IT.
TEN YEARS CONCURRENT
ON ALL CHARGES,
ELIGIBLE IN FIVE,
AND TH YOU
EVERYTHING THEY KNOW.
HE WAS COMING TO SEE YOU.
AT A FLOPHOUSE ON NINTH.
HE WAS SUPPOSED TO BE THERE
BY 7:00.
BUT THIS GUY, HE GOT
THREE-QUARTERS OF A MIL WORTH
OF OUR COKE IN HIS STOMACH,
AND HE DON'T SHOW.
SO WHAT'D YOU DO?
WE WERE GONNA FIND HIM.
LOTS OF 'EM. HEARD
THE SIRENS. LOTS OF 'EM.
WE GO DOWNSTAIRS,
WALK UP THE BLOCK,
AND GUESS WHAT WE SEE.
A BUNCH OF COPS
STARING AT A TREE.
A FRIGGIN' TREE.
THE DUDE WAS IN A TREE.
SO YOU WAITED?
THE ONLY WAY
TO GET THE BODY BACK.
WE COULDN'T GET THE PACKETS
VIA THE USUAL METHOD.
SO YOU IMPROVISED?
DOESN'T MATTER.
HE WAS ALREADY DEAD.
SO WHY'D HE START MULING?
SAME AS ANYONE.
DESPERATION.
(Ryan) IT'S JUST...
(clears throat)
HE DOESN'T SEEM THE TYPE.
ANYBODY'S THE TYPE
YOU PUSH 'EM HARD ENOUGH.
I MEAN, THE GUY OWED.
HE WAS, UH, FOURTH AND LONG
WITH THE CLOCK RUNNING OUT.
WHO WAS HE INTO?
DIDN'T SAY,
BUT HE WAS SCARED.
YOU WANT TO KNOW WHO KILLED HIM,
YOU FIND OUT WHO HE OWED.
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
I'M GONNA NEED MORE.
I'M GONNA NEED TO KNOW
WHO VOUCHED.
VOUCHED?  FOR JOHN ALLEN--
FOR JOHN ALLEN--
OUR VIC, YOUR MULE.
SOMEBODY BROUGHT HIM TO YOU,
SOMEBODY YOU TRUSTED.
OR DO YOU JUST DO BUSINESS
WITH EVERY DESPERATE WHITE BOY
WITH NO HISTORY
OF CRIMINAL ACTIVITY?
HELL, MAN. HOW'D YOU KNOW
HE WASN'T A COP?
(Esposito) GOT THE PRINTOUT.
RON BIGBY.
HE'S A FLOOR TRADER
AT GOLDMAN.
VIC'S WIFE NEVER HEARD
THE NAME.
FOR A GUY WHO ASSESSES RISK
FOR A LIVING,
HE SURE DOES SEEM
TO TAKE A LOT OF 'EM.
YEAH, WELL, LOOK WHERE
IT GOT HIM.
PICK HIM UP.
YOU GOT IT.
(indistinct conversations)
(Beckett) CASTLE.
DEAD?
YEAH.
WAIT. DEAD?
MR. BIGBY, YOU CAN ASK
AS OFTEN AS YOU LIKE.
THE ANSWER IS NOT
GONNA CHANGE.
OH. THAT IS A DAMN SHAME.
THAT IS A DAMN, DAMN SHAME.
I MEAN, DO YOU KNOW
WHO JOHN ALLEN IS? HUH?
HE'S THE NEW WILLY LOMAN.
OKAY?
EVERYMAN VICTIM
OF AN APATHETIC WORLD.
GOD, I SWEAR. SOMEONE SHOULD
WRITE A PLAY.
HEY, DO YOU WRITE PLAYS?
UNPRODUCED.
MR. BIGBY, IT'S COME
TO OUR ATTENTION
THAT YOU RECENTLY OBTAINED
EMPLOYMENT FOR MR. ALLEN
AS A DRUG MULE.
YOU KNOW ABOUT THAT?
YEAH.
AND BAD NEWS, RON.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO FIND
A NEW DEALER.
WHAT'D THEY TELL YOU?
THAT YOU GOT HIM
AN INTRODUCTION
AND THAT YOU VOUCHED
FOR MR. ALLEN.
OKAY, LOOK.
HE--HE CAME TO ME DESPERATE,
ALL RIGHT?
HE--HE REMEMBERED A STORY I TOLD
ONE NIGHT AT THE TABLE. (sniffs)
THE TABLE?
YEAH, POKER TABLE.
WE'RE IN ONE OF
THE FLOATING GAMES AROUND TOWN.
YOU KNOW, SMALL STAKES, RIGHT?
BUT GOOD WAY TO BLOW OFF STEAM.
BUT THEN WHEN HE GOT LAID OFF,
IT STOPPED BEING A GAME.
HE STARTED BETTING
TO MAKE UP HIS PAYCHECK,
BUT THE STAKES WERE TOO LOW.T .
THE MOB-RUN GAMES.
YEAH, TRIADS. HE DID FINE
FOR A BIT, YOU KNOW?
BUT... (scoffs)
LUCK'S A FICKLE BITCH.
HE LOST MORE THAN HE HAD
TO THE WRONG GUY.
HE COULDN'T MAKE ENOUGH
TO COVER HIS LOSSES.
YEAH, THAT'S WHEN HE REMEMBERED
THE NIGHT I TOLD THE STORY
ABOUT MY OWN FISCAL EMERGENCY,
ABOUT HOW I WENT TO MEXICO,
MADE 50 GRAND IN ONE DAY.
(chuckles)
THAT'S WHEN I FIGURED,
HEY, WHAT THE HELL?
JUST PAY IT FORWARD.
ALL RIGHT,
THIS GUY THAT HE OWED--
DID HE GIVE YOU
A DESCRIPTION, NAME?
NO NAME.
JOHN THOUGHT
HE WAS RUSSIAN MAFIA
BECAUSE OF A
BECAUSE OF ALL HIS TATTOOS.
(Ryan) IF SOME TATTED-UP
RUSSIAN MOBSTER WAS AFTER ME,
I COULD SEE TAKING A JOB
AS A DRUG MULE.
(Esposito) A TATTOOED RUSSIAN
IN NEW YORK CITY?
WELL, THAT NARROWS IT DOWN.
WE CONDUCT
AN INVESTIGATION
BASED ON THE INFORMATION
WE HAVE,
NOT THE EVIDENCE WE NEED.
WELL, BIGBY SAYS THAT
THE RUSSIAN HANGS OUT
AT THE CLUB AT CHINATOWN.
WHY DON'T WE JUST GO THERE?
THE GAMES ARE
WORD OF MOUTH, BRO.
THEY DON'T JUST SHARE
WITH COPS.
WELL, LUCKILY,
I'M NOT A COP.
CASTLE.
WHAT? IT'S PERFECT.
I GO IN, SCOPE THE PLACE OUT
UNTIL I I.D. THE RUSSIAN.
HEY, YOU KNOW, THAT'S NOT
A BAD PLAN.
WE STILL HAVE TO FIND
THE GAME.
LEAVE THAT TO ME.
(laughs) THAT'S
A PRETTY GOOD STORY, RICKY.
IT'S GOT A BIG OPENING,
MAJOR TWIST.
THOUGH I GOTTA SAY, I SAW THAT
WHOLE DRUG MULE THING COMING.
YE.
NICE TRY, CONNELLY. YOU'RE NOT
GONNA GOAD ME INTO RAISING.
STEPHEN, YOU ONCE WROTE ABOUT
AN UNDERGROUND POKER GAME
IN, UH, "KING CON."
YEAH?
AND YOU ONCE HAD HARRY BOSCH
INVESTIGATE THE MURDER
OF A POKER PLAYER.
YEAH, "ONE DOLLAR JACKPOT."
WHY?
WELL, MICHAEL, THIS GUY
THAT WE'RE LOOKING FOR,
HE'S A REGULAR IN THE TRIAD-RUN
GAMES IN CHINATOWN.
I THOUGHT MAYBE ONE OF YOU KNEW
SOMEONE WHO COULD GET ME IN.
WHAT, ARE YOU NUTS?
THOSE ARE CROOKS
AND KILLERS DOWN THERE.
LOOK, RICKY, DOING
THE RESEARCH IS ONE THING,
BUT THE RUSSIAN MAFIA,
THE TRIAD?
YOU TANGLE WITH THOSE PEOPLE,
AND ALL THE BEST SELLERS
IN THE WORLD
ARE NOT GONNA PROTECT YOU.
OH, NO. I DON'T PLAN
ON TANGLING.
I'M JUST GONNA BE ANOTHER
RICH, BORED THRILL SEEKER
LOOKING TO TRY MY LUCK
DOWN THERE.
YOU MUST REALLY LIKE HER.
WHO?
THAT POLICE DETECTIVE
OF YOURS.
LOOK, RICKY,
THERE'S ONLY ONE REASON
THAT YOU'D BE DUMB ENOUGH
TO GO DOWN THERE,
AND THAT'S TO IMPRESS A GIRL.
NOW WHY DON'T YOU
CUT YOURSELF A LITTLE SLACK
AND JUST BUY HER
SOME FLOWERS?
DO YOU KNOW THE PLACE OR NOT?
WELL?
(people speaking
in foreign language)
ARE YOU SURE
THIS IS THE PLACE?
CANNELL HAS NEVER
STEERED ME WRONG.
IN PLACE          OKAY.TON S
(Esposito) BUTTON CAM'S
STEEIN PLACE, RYAN.
GOOD FOR PICTURE AND...
(feedback whines)
AH, SOUND.
ALL RIGHT, SO REMEMBER,
WE CAN HEAR YOU,
BUT YOU CAN'T HEAR US.
SO ONCE YOU LEAVE THIS VAN,
YOU'RE ON YOUR OWN, OKAY?
ALL RIGHT, TELL ME
THE PLAN AGAIN.
I GO IN, I FIND
THE TATTOOED RUSSIAN,
I GET A CLEAR PICTURE OF HIM,
AND I GET THE HELL OUT OF THERE.
AND YOU DON'T STAY
ANY LONGER THAN YOU NEED TO.
I'LL BE FINE.
BESIDES, IT'S CHINATOWN.
HOW MANY RUSSIAN POKER PLAYERS
CAN THERE BE?
(people speaking
foreign language)
ANYBODY ELSE HAVE
A BAD FEELING ABOUT THIS?
YEAH.
YEAH,
THAT'S WHAT I THOUGHT.
(man laughing)
(speaking foreign language)
(man speaks
foreign language)
(man speaks foreign language)
GO AHEAD AND DEAL.
(indistinct conversations)
(whispers) I'M IN.
(man speaks foreign language)
(singsongy) TATTOOED RUSSIAN.
(normal voice) PAY DIRT.
(indistinct conversations)
(men speaking foreign language)
UH, THERE'S
ANOTHER TATTOOED RUSSIAN.
THERE'S A WHOLE TABLE
OF TATTOOED RUSSIANS.
APPARENTLY
THERE ARE A LOT MORE RUSSIANS
IN CHINATOWN THAN I THOUGHT.
♪
[ Female Announcer ] MAY YOUR
HOLIDAYS BE MERRY AND BRIGHT.
MERRY PRINGLES.
THAT'S WHY NEW
Dove Style + Care
NOURISHES ANFree Cream Serum
NOURISHES AND CONDITIONS,
FREE FROM HAIR SMOOTH SHINY
AND FREE FROM FLYAWAYS.
NEW Dove Style + Care
Frizz Free Cream Serum.
BETTER STYLE
THROUGH BETTER CARE.
♪ DON'T KNOW WHAT I'D DO
♪ I'D HAVE NOTHING TO PROVE
♪ I'D HAVE NOTHING TO LOSE
♪ I'D BE ALL LOST AT SEA
♪ WITH NO REASON
TO MAKE IT THROUGH ♪
[ Male Announcer ]
INTRODUCING THE Celebration
Diamond Collection.
♪ IF IT WASN'T FOR YOU
[ Male Announc,
WE GUARANTEE THEM FOR LIFE.
Zales IS THE DIAMOND STORE.
LET LOVE SHINE.
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
YOUR FAVORITE HOLIDAY FLAVORS
ARE HERE...
WITH SOME NEW ONES TO LOVE.
♪
TRY NEW SUGAR FREE
PUMPKIN SPICE...
AND PECAN PRALINE.
THE GIFT OF GREAT TASTE
IS JUST A CLICK AWAY.
GET YOUR COUPON
AT TASTELIFT.COFFEE-MATE.COM.
NESTLE.
GOOD FOOD. GOOD LIFE.
I'VE BEEN FORTUNATE TO WIN
ON GOLF'S BIGGEST STAGES.
BUT WHEN JOINT PAIN
AND STIFFNESS
FROM PSORIATIC ARTHRITIS HIT,
EVEN THE SMALLEST THINGS
BECAME DIFFICULT.
I FINALLY UNDERSTOOD WHAT
SERIOUS JOINT PAIN IS LIKE.
I TALKED TO MY RHEUMATOLOGIST
AND HE PRESCRIBED Enbrel.
Enbrel CAN HELP RELIEVE
PAIN, STIFFNESS,
AND STOP JOINT DAMAGE.
BECAUSE Enbrel, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS,
SOMETIMES FATAL EVENTS
INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS,
LYMPHOMA, OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING Enbrel,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START Enbrel IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
,
DON'T START Enbrel IF YOU HAVE
AN INFHAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,R SO,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON Enbrel, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING, OR PALENESS.
[ Phil ]
GET BACK TO THE THINGS
THAT MATTER MOST.
ASK YOUR RHEUMATOLOGIST
IF Enbrel IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
[ Doctor ]
Enbrel, THE NUMBER ONE
BIOLOG MEDICINE
PRESCRIBED BY RHEUMATOLOGISTS.
[ Doctor ]
Enbrel, THE NUMBER ONE
BIOLOG MEDICINE
(indistinct conversations)
SO... THE RUSSIANS
ARE REGULARS HERE,
BUT ONLY A HANDFUL PLAY
AT THE NO-LIMIT TABLE,
WHICH IS WHERE JOHN ALLEN
WOULD'VE GONE.
THE GUY SAID THEY'RE
CARD BULLIES, PUSHING UP POTS,
FORCING THEIR OPPONENTS TO BT
MORE JUST TO STAY IN THE GAM.
YOU THINK HE HAS ANY IDEA
HE'S RECAPPING A CONVERSATION
THAT WE JUST HEARD
IN ITS ENTIRETY?
GIVE THE GUY A GADGET,
HE THINKS HE'S BOND.
LET'S JUST HOPE HE REMEMBERS
HE'S WEARING A CAMERA
BEFORE HE GOES
AND TAKES A LEAK.
WHY WOULD YOU EVEN--
TRUST ME.
...COMING THROUGH,
BUT I GOTTA STIR IT UP.
I'M GONNA GO SIT AT THE TABLE,
SEE IF I CAN FIND
ANYTHING OUT.
WHAT DID HE SAY?
HE JUST SAID
HE'S TAKING A SEAT--
THAT'S NOT THE PLAN.
THAT'S NOT THE PLAN, CASTLE!
HOW'S IT GOING?
THIS IS NO-LIMIT TABLE.
WHICH IS PERFECT, BECAUSE I AM
A NO-LIMIT KINDA GUY.
(chuckles)
CHANGE FOR $20,000, PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT, FELLAS.
DEAL ME IN.
(Beckett) NO, NO, NO, NO,
NO, NO. WHAT'S HE DOING?
DROPPING HALF MY YEARLY SALARY
LIKE IT WAS POCKET CHANGE.
(man chuckles)
NICE TATS.
TA--NO, TATTOOS.
THE TAT--IT'S NICE.
WHAT DO THEY SAY?
IT SAYS
MIND YOUR OWN BUSINESS
AND PLAY CARDS.
SORRY. DON'T MEAN TO PRY.
I'M JUST, UH, I'M ACTUALLY
JUST A WRITER.
I'M JUST DOING
A LITTLE BIT OF RESEARCH.
(man) WRITER, HU?
ANYTHING, UH,
WE MIGHT HAVE HEARD OF?
UH, "STORM FALL,"
"STORM'S LAST STAND."
DERRICK STORM.
YEAH.
I LOVE THIS GUY.
WHY DID YOU KILL HIM?
IT'S A LONG STORY,
BUT I'M WORKING ON A NEW ONE
ABOUT, UH, UNDERGROUND POKER.
VERY HUSH-HUSH.
JUST KINDA CAME DOWN TO GET
A FEEL FOR THE WORLD, YOU KNOW?
AND YOU'RE--YOU WANT TO TRY
TO BE AUTHENTIC?
EXACTLY.
NO PROBLEM)
(speaking Russian)
(men chuckle)
(man speaks Russian)
(chuckles) YEAH.
(Esposito) SEEMS LIKE
HE'S MAKING FRIENDS.
THEY JUST SAID
THEY'RE GONNA TAKE HIM
FOR EVERYTHING HSPEAK RUSSI?
SEMESTER IN KIEV
BETWEEN JUNIOR AND SENIOR YEAR.
(imitates Russian accent)
SOMETIMES WHEN I AM BORED,
I GOT TO GLECHIK CAFé
IN LITTLE ODESSA
AND PRETEND TO BE MUSCOVITE.
NOW THAT'S KINDA HOT.
RAISE.
(chip clatters)
CALL.
(clatters)
I CALL.
(grunts)
(groans)
(joints crack)
CHECK THE PLAYERS' HANDS.
SEE IF THERE'S ANYTHING
THAT'LL EXPLAIN THE BRUISE
PATTERNS ON OUR VIC'S NECK.
(groans)
(sighs)
CALL.
(chip clatters)
(clears throat)
SAY, MR. CASTLE,
TELL ME LITTLE BIT MORE
A, UH, RUSSIAN MOBSTER BOOK.H, T
WITH A TASTE FOR CARDS.
HE, UH, PREYS
OFF OF DESPERATION,
LURING PEOPLE IN TO BET HIM
MORE THAN THEY HAVE.
(clicks tongue)
AND WHY WOULD HE DO THIS?
BECAUSE HE'S ALSO
A LOAN SHARK.
SEE, HE FRONTS HIS VICTIMS,
AND MAKES BANK ON...
WHAT THE HELL IS HE DOING?
HE ONE OF THESE GUYS
INTO GIVING UP THEIR HAND. GIVIE
OR HE'S TRYING TO TIP OFF
OUR KILLER.
BUT THERE'S ONE GUY,
A FAMILY GUY, HE GETS IN
A LITTLE TOO DEEP,
ACK.
SO THE MOBSTER...
GOT NO CHOICE.
HAS TO KILL HIM,
SEND A MESSAGE
TO ANYONE ELSE WHO OWES HIM.
SO ONE NIGHT... HE LURES HIM
INTO AN ABANDONED BUILDING,
STRANGLES HIM TO DEATH
AND THROWS HIM OFF THE ROOF.
SOUNDS LIKE LOT OF WORK.
WHY NOT JUST PUT BULLET
IN HIS HEAD?
IT'S MUCH MORE SIMPL.
(laughs)
BANG.
OH, MY...
(laughs)
HEY, RYAN,
CHECK THIS OUT.
WHAT IS HE DOING
WITH HIS FINGER?
(Beckett) PUNCH IN ON THAT.
IT'S A PROSTHETIC.MARK ON.
THAT'S OUR GUY.
HEY, IF HE THINKS CASTLE'S
A THREAT, HE'S--
WE GOTTA GET HIM
OUTTA THERE, NOW.
THEIR SECURITY'S
PRETTY WELL ARMED.
WE GO IN THERE AS COPS,
IT MIGHT GET MESSY.
OH, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
UH, I'M GONNA GO IN THERE,
AND IF I'M NOT OUT
IN TEN MINUTES,
YOU GUYS CALL FOR BACKUP.
CAN I HAVE MY PURSE, PLEASE?
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO,
LIP GLOSS 'EM TO DEATH?
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
[ Female Announcer ]
At Yoplait,
we want you to feel
even better
about your favorite flavors.
So when you call, tweet,
and post, we listen.
That's why Yoplait Light
and Yoplait Original
are now made with
no high fructose corn syrup.
And why we use
only natural colors
and natural flavors
in Yoplait Original.
So, anything else we can do
for you, let us know.
But you'll keep it
to yogurt, right?
'Cause we shouldn't really help
with your love life.
Yoplait. It is so good!
FOR STRONG BEAUTIFUL HAIR.
-IT TURNS OUT...
-WE WERE WORKING AT...
AT THE WRONG END OF HAIR.
[ Male Announcer ]
INTRODUCING CLEAR.
IT FEEDS YOUR SCALP.
CLEAR GIVES YOU STRONGER
MORE BEAUTIFUL HAIR.
[ Heidi ] CLEAR SCALP
AND HAIR BEAUTY THERAPY.
CLEAR GIVES YOU STRONGER
MORE BEAUTIFUL HAIR.
(man speaks foreign language)
(imitating Russian accent)
OH, COME ON, BOYS.
MY BOYFRIEND IS WAITING.
HE IS PLAYER.
IF I DON'T GO INSIDE,
HE WILL LOSE.
I'M HIS LUCKY CHARM, YOU KNOW?
NO?
WELL, MAYBE I CAN BE
A LUCKY CHARM FOR YOU.
WE WIN, AND WHEN I AM IN THERE,
WE ALWAYS WIN,
AND THEN MAYBE I CAN SHARE
SOME OF MY BOYFRIEND'S LUCK
WITH YOU.
HMM.
ALL IN.
IT'S A BIG POT,
MR. WRITER MAN...
ALL THAT MONEY.
BUT THEN, WHAT IS MONEY
TO MILLIONAIRE, HUH?
YOU JUST CAN WRITE IT OFF
ON YOUR TAXESH, DO.
UH, AS, UH, DOING RESEARCH.
ALL IN.
HMM. (chuckles)
YOU AR
YOU ARE LIKE CHARACTER
IN YOUR BOOK...
IN TOO DEEP.
THREE QUEENS.
THAT'S VERY IMPRESSIVE.
NOT A LOT
CAN BEAT THREE QUEENS.
EXCEPT AN INSIDE STRAIGHT,
MAYBE.
SWEETHEART, THIS IS FOR YOU.
WOULD YOU CHANGE THIS
INTO SOMETHING A LITTLE SMALLER
THAT I CAN CARRY?
NOW THAT
IS A BIG PILE OF MONEY.
BUT WHAT'S MONEY
TO A MOBSTER, RIGHT?
(gun action clicks)
WALK.
WHOA! WHOA! WHOA!
WHO ARE YOU?
I TOLD YOU,
I'M--I'M A NOVELIST.
THE STORY--THE DEAD MAN,
THE ROOF, WHO TOLD YOU?
WHO KNOWS?
HIS FAMILY KNOWS,
HIS CHILDREN KNOW.
IF HE PAID WHAT HE OWED,
HE'D BE HOME WITH THEM NOW.
BUT HE CROSSED ME.
AND NOW YOU HAVE CROSSED ME.
NO, NO, NO,
I'M JUST A WRITER.
DO NOT LIE. YOU'RE A COP.
(imitating Runt)
HIM, A COP?
DON'T MAKE ME LAUGH.
HE'S BARELY EVEN A MAN.
BECKETT?
BUT YOU ARE A MAN,
AREN'T YOU?
A VERY HANDSOME MAN.
RICHARD, ARE YOU BOTHERING
THIS HANDSOME MAN?
GO AWAY.
OKAY, BOYS AND THEIR GUNS.
AM I SUPPOSED TO BE IMPRESSED?
IT DOESN'T CONCERN YOU.
ACTUALLY... (grunts)
(groans)  AH!roans).
(whispering) IS IT
JUST MY IMAGINATION,
OR DID YOU CHANGE?
CASTLE, COULD YOU GET
SOME BACKUP, PLEASE?
YEAH.
(whispering)
SHH, SHH, SHH. QUIET.
YEAH.
THANK YOU.
THIS WAY.
(exhales deeply)
SO HOW IS SHE?
IT'S HARD WHEN EVERYTHING
YOU THOUGHT YOU KNEW
TURNS OUT TO BE A LIE.
WELL, NOT EVERYTHING
WAS A LIE.
NOT HER HUSBAND'S LOVE.
I MEAN, SOMETIMES
WE DO THE WRONG THINGSONS.FOR T.
SO CASE IS CLOSED.
I GUESS YOUR "COSMO" STORY
GETS A HA
.
SPEAKING OF HAPPY ENDINGS...
THANKS FOR SAVING MY LIFE.
I WAS JUST TRYING
TO AVOID PAPERWORK.
YEAH. WE MAKE
A PRETTY GOOD TEAM, YOU KNOW?
LIKE STARSKY AND HUTCH,
TANGO AND CASH,
TURNER AND HOOCH.
YOU KNOW,
NOW THAT YOU MENTION IT,
YOU DO REMIND ME
A LITTLE OF HOOCH.
MM.
IT'S BECAUSE YOU'RE AFRAID,
ISN'T IT?
YOU'RE AFRAID THAT IF YOU LOOK
IN TO YOUR MOTHER'S DEATH,
THAT YOU WILL GO BACK DOWN
THAT RABBIT HOLE
AND LOSE YOURSELF AGAIN.
BUT IT'S DIFFERENT THIS TIME.
WE HAVE GO
WE HASTRONG    LEADS.
AND YOU WON'T
HAVE TO DO IT ALONE.
WE CAN DO IT TOGETHER.
WHAT IF I DON'T WANT
TO KNOW?
DID YOU EVER THINK OF THAT?
WHAT IF I'M NOT READY?
WHAT IF THE IDEA OF CATCHING
MY MOM'S MURDERER
AND THEN HAVING TO SIT THERE
AND WATCH AS HE CUTS SOME DEAL
THAT PUTS HIM BACK OUT
ON THE STREET IN TEN YEARS
MAKES ME NAUSEOUS?
YOU DREDGED UP MY PAST
FOR YOU, CASTLE, NOT FOR ME.
AND YOU'RE TOO SELFISH
TO EVEN SEE IT.SEL
THE CASE IS CLOSED, CASTLE.
WE MADE A DEAL,
AND I EXPECT YOU TO HONOR IT.
YOU'RE WRITING.
IT'S TIME.
AND BECKETT?
M SORRY, DAD.
I'M SORRY, DAD.
SO HOW WAS THE MOVIE?
WE DIDN'T GO.
WHY NOT?
OWEN.
WHAT HAPPENED?
HE WAS PLAYING VIDEO GAMES
AND LOST TRACK OF TI
BY THE TIME HE SHOWED UP,
IT WAS TOO LATE.
(sighs) SORRY, SWEETIE.
AND THEN
WHEN HE DID SHOW UP,
HE TRIED TO ACT LIKE
IT'S NO BIG DEAL,
LIKE I'M OVERREACTING.
I MEAN, HE DIDN'T EVEN CALL.
WHY DO BOYS DO THAT?
WHY DO THEY ALWAYS HAVE TO
JUSTIFY EVERYTHING?
WHY CAN'T THEY JUST SAY
THEY'RE SORRY?
(Lex Land's "My Fault.
Your Mistake." playing)
THANK YOU.
FOR WHAT?
FOR JUST... BEING YOU.
♪ YOU GAVE ME GOOD STEPS
TO FOLLOW ♪
♪ AND I WISH I...
I'M SORRY.
WHAT I DID WAS WRONG.
I VIOLATED YOUR TRUST,
I OPENED OLD WOUNDS,
ECT
YOUR WISHES.
AND IF WE'RE NOT GONNA SEE
EACH OTHER AGAIN,
THEN YOU DESERVE TO
♪ AND I'M SORRY THAT I...
I'M VERY, VERY SORRY.
♪ BUT YOUR LITTLE GIRL
♪ IS GONNA CHANGE THE WORLD
SEE ♪
♪ YOU'LL SEE
CASTLE.
♪
I'LL SEE YOU TOMORROW.
♪ YOU'LL SEE
I CAN'T TAKE ANYMORE.
I JUST CAME BACK FROM A RUN
ON THE BEACH ALONE.
I HAD LUNCH ALONE.
I RAN MY ERRANDS
OVER THE WEEKEND ALONE.
IT IS WHAT IT IS.
WHAT DOES THAT EVEN MEAN?
I WANT MY FRIEND BACK.
WELL, THAT COULD BE TOUGH,
THE WAY YOU SANDBAGGED HER.
WE HAVE TO FIX THIS.
MAYBE...
MAYBE SAM AND NAOMI
SHOULD WORK TOGETHER.
MAYBE THAT'S THE ANSWER.
MAYBE IT IS WHAT IT IS.
YOU KNOW WHAT? THERE'S
SOMETHING WRONG WITH YOU.
I'M CALLING VIOLET.
NO, DON'T--DON'T CALL VIOLET.
HELLO?
WE HAVE TO DO SOMETHING.