UH, YOU WANT TO PLAY?
WELL, LET'S GET READY.
$1,000 "TO"
SONG -- YOU ALL SETTLED?
"SONG LYRICS" IS THE CATEGORY,
AND HERE WE GO.
[ BELL CHIMES ]
ANTHONY.
SWEET LAND OF LIBERTY.
THAT'S IT.
YOU GOT $1,000.
YES, SIR.
ANTHONY MYLES.
MARRERO, LOUISIANA.
YOU'RE GOING TO SCHOOL, RIGHT?
YES, SIR.
LOUISIANA STATE UNIVERSITY.
YEAH. SOPHOMORE?
YES, SIR. GO, TIGERS.
UM, MAJORING IN
POLITICAL SCIENCE.
MM-HMM.
YUM, READY FOR THE SCHOOL YEAR.
WHAT'S AN AMBASSADOR?GERS.
YOU'RE AN L.S.U. AMBASSADOR.
WE BASICALLY SERVE THE SCHOOL.
WE RECRUIT OR -- AND ADVISE.
WE HELP 'EM OUT WITH TOURS
AND DO ANYTHING
THE SCHOOL ASKS US TO DO.
MANAGER -- MANAGER
FOR THE BASKETBALL TEAM.
YEP.
UM, I WORK WITH NIKKI CALDWELL.
SHE JUST CAME
FROM U.C.L.A. UP THE ROAD.
AND YOUR STUDIES
ARE GOING WELL.
YEAH, YEAH. YEP.
I'M INVOLVED,
AND I'M DOING GOOD IN SCHOOL.
GOOD. ALL RIGHT.
NICE TO HAVE YOU HERE, ANTHONY.
THANK YOU.
GOOD LUCK TO YOU
THE REST OF THE WAY HERE.
HI, JODY.
HELLO, PAT.
SO YOU'RE
JODY LUNDQUIST, HUH?
I AM.
UH, FROM PHOENIX...
FROM PHOENIX, ARIZONA.
...WHICH IS IN ARIZONA,
RIGHT, EXACTLY.
YES.
UH, WHAT DO YOU DO THERE?
I DO LANDSCAPE
AND PRESERVATION WORK...
MM-HMM.
...ON FORECLOSED HOMES.
OH, OKAY. UH, NOW YOU'RE
FROM CHICAGO ORIGINALLY?
I'M ORIGINALLY
FROM CHICAGO.
HOW LONG AGO
DID YOU MAKE THE MOVE?
10 YEARS NOW.
YEAH. ENJOYING LIFE,
I TAKE IT, IN PHOENIX?
NO, I HATE THE H
DO YOU REALLY?
I REALLY DO.
I MISS CHICAGO.
OH.
GO, CUBS.
[ LAUGHS ] ALL RIGHT, WELL,
I HOPE YOU, UH, WE'LL --
WE'LL FAN YOU DOWN OCCASIONALLY
EAT.
GETS TOO WARM IN HERE.WELL,
I HOPE YOU, UH, WE'LL --
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
HI, TAMMY.
HI. HOW ARE YOU?
I'M FINE. THANKS.
UH, TAMMY WALKER,
HIXSON, TENNESSEE, HUH?
YEAH.
WHAT PART OF THE STATE
IF IT D THAT BE?
IT'S, UM, JUST OUTSIDE --
IT'S PART OF CHATTANOOGA,
ONE OF THE SUBURBS.
OKAY. GOTCHA.
UH, YOU ARE MARRIED.
I AM.
I'VE BEEN MARRIED
TO MY GREAT HUSBAND, MICHAEL.
UM, I HAVE ONE DAUGHTER, GROWN.
I HAVE FOUR
BEAUTIFUL GRANDCHILDREN --
JONATHAN, CONNOR,
SYDNEY, AND CAMILLE...
YEAH.
...'CAUSE IF I DON'T SAY THAT,
THEY'LL KI
OH, I KNOW.
AND WE CAN'T HAVE
"GRANDMA-CIDE" GOING ON.
[ LAUGHS ]
UH, YOU WORK.
I DO.
I'M A FULL-TIME CAREGIVER
AND A PART-TIME TAX PREPARER.
OH. AND YOU DO ZIP-LINING.
IS THAT THE THING
WHERE YOU GO DOWN THE...
YEAH, OVER THE TREETOPS...
WOW.
...AND YOU'RE LIKE, "WHOO!"
YOU KNOW.
UH, ADY TO PLAY
SOME MORE HERE?
I AM.
UH, LET'S GET READY, $2,000 THIS
TIME FOR OUR NEXT "TOSS UP."
UH, THE CATEGORY
IS "LIVING THING."
[ BELL CHIMES ]
ANTHONY.
BOSTON TERRIER.
THAT'S IT. YOU GOT IT IN THERE.
GOOD FOR YOU.
, YOU GOT 'EM BOTH.
YOU HAVE $3,000.
YOU KNOW, IT OCCURS TO ME
THE ONLY ZIP-LINING I DO
IS ACTUALLY SEALING
MY KIDS' SANDWICHES.
THAT'S IT.
UH, JIM, WHAT DO YOU HAVE?
HANG IN THERE, PAT.
TONIGHT'S JACKPOT ROUND
IS BROUGHT TO YOU BY
EGGLAND'S BEST EGGS.
WANT TO GIVE YOUR FAMILY
THE BEST IN NUTRITION?
THE ONLY EGGS TO GIVE THEM
ARE EGGLAND'S BEST,
HIGH IN VITAMINS D, E,
B12, AND OMEGA-3s
AND LOADED WITH
DELICIOUS FARM-FRESH TASTE.
EGGLAND'S BEST.
AND HERE   TONIGHT'S.
ENCOUNTER TRUE LUXURY
AT THE PALACE HOTEL,
SAN FRANCISCO'S MOST ELEGANT
AND HISTORIC HOTEL.
'S
IN 1875,
THIS LANDMARK OFFERS
THE GRANDEUR OF A BYGONE ERA
WITH MODERN COMFORT.
VISIT sfpalace.com.
ALL RIGHT.
THE CATEGORY FOR THIS ROUND
IS "SAME LETTER."
YOU KNOW WHAT THAT MEANS.
EVERY WORD IN THE PUZZLE
STARTS WITH THE SAME LETTER.
UH, ANTHONY, YOU'LL SPIN.
Tammy:
LET'S GO, ANTHONY.
WELL, THAT -- WELL, GET IT
OUT OF YOUR SYSTEM EARLY.
JODY, YOUR TURN.
COME ON, JODY.
N.
THERE ARE FOUR N's.
Tammy: WHOO!
BUT THEY'RE NOT
THAT INITIAL LETTER,
SO THAT STILL REMAINS
TO BE FOUND.
YOU HAVE $1,200.
I'D LIKE TO BUY AN E.
YES, TWO E's.
THEREHUH.HAT
HALF A
[ HORN HONKS ]
MAY I HAVE AN S?
UH, YES, YOU MAY HAVE 4 S's.
THAT'S WORTH $2,000.
YOU CAN PICK THAT UP.
[ LAUGHS ]
T.
THERE IS ONE T.
MAY I BUY AN A, PLEASE?
THERE ARE FOUR A's.
YEAH.
THERE'S ANOTHER "HALF KIA"
OUT THERE,
AND SHE'S GONNA BE CLOSE TO IT,
AND LOOK AT THAT.
[ HORN HONKS ]
NOW -- WHOA.
DON'T TOUCH THAT KIA.
OH, SORRY.
[ LAUGHS ]
[ LAUGHS ] NO, THAT'S OKAY.
YOU HAVE TO PICK A LETTER FIRST.
L.
WHAT'S THAT?
OKAY, NOW YOU CAN
TOUCH YOUR CAR.
THERE YOU GO. PICK I
YOU GOT BOTH HALVES.
NOW AS YOU KNOW, YOU HAVE TO BE
THE ONE WHO SOLVES THIS PUZZLE
BEFORE HITTING A BANKRUPT
IN ORDER TO CLAIM THAT CAR.
WHAT DO YOU WANT
T UP.NEXT?
BUY AN I.
THREE I's.
MAY I HAVE AN --
OR MTO DO UY AN O?
YOU MAY, YES.
THERE'S ONE O.
YOU CAN BUY ANOTHER
IF YOU WANT.
WELL, THEN I'LL BUY A U.
AY I BGHT, AND SHE DOES THAT
BECAUSE THAT'S THE LAST VOWEL,
SO WE KNOW
IT'S UP THERE SOMEWHERE.
THERE IT IS.
THEY'RE ALL GONE NOW.
THAT'S A GOOD THING TO HAVE
RIGHT NOW...
R.
KIND OF A SAFETY NET.
OH, THERE'
YOU'RE DOING JUST FINE.
M.
YES. [ LAUGHS ]
THERE'S AN M.
[ LAUGHS ]
NICE JOB.
B.
YEAH, WELL,
WE'RE ALMOST THERE. [ LAUGHS ]
[ LAUGHS ]
OKAY. THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
I HAVE TO SPIN.
ALL RIGHT.
D.
YEAH, THERE'S A D.
PICK THAT UP.
OH!
YES. YOU WANT TO DO IT?
YOU WANT TO SOLVE IT?
YES, PLEASE.
OKAY.
SENSATIONAL SUBMARINE SANDWICH.
THERE YOU GO.
[ LAUGHS ]
PLEASE, I'M GETTING
TOO OLD FOR THIS. [ LAUGHS ]
THAT WAS -- YOU KNOW,
YOU JUST WANTED MORE STUFF.
I DID.
YOU PRETENDED YOU DIDN'T KNOW IT
FOR A VERY LONG TIME.
[ LAUGHS ]
UH, T THE GIFT TAG
AND BUT -- BUT MORE IMPORTANT,
LOOK AT THIS.
LET'S HEAR
ABOUT THIS PRIZE.
[ LAUGHS ]
CONGRATULATIONS, JODY!
YOU'VE JUST WON A NEW KIA SOUL.
THE KIA SOUL LOOKS DIFFERENT
BECAUSE IT IS DIFFERENT
WITH AN ARRAY OF COOL COLORS,
MORE THAN 40 ACCESSORIES,
NS OF TECHNOLOGY.
THE SOUL -- A NEW WAY TO ROLL.
$15,000.
I MENTIONED THE "GIFT TAG"
AND THE CASH.
WE ADD EVERYTHING UP,
AND YOU NOW HAVE $20,500.
NOW YOU CAN RELAX, I THINK.
ARE YOU CAPABLE OF DOING THAT?
I'LL TRY.
ALL RIGHT. OKAY.
[ LAUGHS ]
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK. WE'RE GONNA
HOSE HER DOWN. STAY WITH US.
WELL, YOU MADE THAT EXCITING.
I'LL SAY THAT MUCH.
Announcer:
NEW UNISOM NATURAL NIGHTS
SOOTHES YOU TO SLEEP
WITH INGREDIENTS LIKE MELATO
IT'S SAFE, WITH NO SIDE EFFECTS,
SO YOU WAKE UP...
READY TO GO.
UNISOM NATURAL NIGHTS.
MY DRY HANDS USED TO
GIVE AWAY MY AGE.
Announcer: NEW GOLD BOND
INTENSIVE HAND CREAM.
NOW MY HANDS LOOK GREAT.
Announcer:
GOLD BOND INTENSIVE HAND CREAM.
THIS STUFF REALLY WORKS!
WELCOME BACK.
KIA'S NOT ON THE WHEEL.
THE "HALF KIAS"
AREN'T OUT THERE
BECAUSE SOMEBODY
ALREADY WON THE DARN THING.
UH, "PHRASE" IS THE CATEGORY
FOR THIS ROUND...
[ BELL CHIMES ]
AND IT'S A PRIZE PUZZLE.
AND HERE'S THE PERSON
WHO WON THE CAR
WHO'S GONNA START THIS ROUND.
GO AHEAD, JODY.
N.
YEAH, ONE N.
$400 -- NO, $550.
G.
PRICES ARE UP.
ONE G.
MAY I BUY AN I?
YOU MAY.
AND THERE IS AN I.
IN FACT, THERE'S A SECOND ONE
COMING UP, AS WELL.
T.
ONE T.
MAY I BUY AN E?
ONE E.
H.
YEAH, THERE ARE TWO H's.
YOU KIND OF MAKE DECISIONS
ON THE FLY HERE.
[ LAUGHS ]
S.
YES. TWO S's.
MAY I BUY AN A?
MM-HMM.
THREE A's.
SMOOTH -- OH.
MAY -- MAY I SOLVE THE PUZZLE?
[ LAUGHS ]
WELL, YOU -- YOU SEEM
TO WANT TO. GO AHEAD.
SMOOTH SAILING AHEAD.
YEAH, THAT'S IT.
[ LAUGHS ]
YOU'RE AN ADVENTURER.
YOU'RE GOING ON
A CARIBBEAN CRUISE.
[ LAUGHS ]
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
[ LAUGHS ]
JODY, EXPERIENCE
THE CARIBBEAN IN STYLE
WITH M.S.C. CRUISES.
ENJOY TRUE ITALIAN ELEGANCE
AND LUXURIOUS ACCOMMODATIONS
AS YOU EXPLORE THE ISLANDS
OF YOUR DREAMS.
THE WORLD IS YOURS TO EXPLORE
WITH M.S.C. CRUISES.
TONIGHT'S
WINNING SPIN I.D. NUMBER --
SH3631303 --
BELONGS TO SANDRA H.
YOU HAVES 24 HOURS
TO LOG ON TO wheeloffortune.com
AND CLAIM YOUR EXOTIC
CARIBBEAN CRUISE.
HOW YOU DOING?
I'M DOING VERY WELL.
THANK YOU.
OH, GOOD. GOOD.
ARE YOU HAVING ATIME?
I'M HAVING
A WONDERFUL TIME.
IT'S HARD TO TELL.
UH, $28,100 IS WHAT SHE HAS.
WE HAVE A MESSAGE.
TONIGHT'S MYSTERY ROUND
IS OVERFLOWING WITH GREEN...
VERY NICE.
"BEFORE & AFTER"
IS THE CATEGORY.
TAMMY, WOULD YOU
LIKE TO SPIN?
I WOULD LOVE TO.
WE'D LOVE TO SEE YOU DO IT.
R.
THERE YOU GO, TWO R's.
GOOD START FOR YOU.
WHOO!
I'LL BUY A VOWEL.
MM-HMM.
AN E.
YES, ONE E.
I'LL BUY ANOTHER VOW
AN I.
THERE ARE FOUR I's.
WHOO!
YOU'RE ON A FREEEL.
NOW.
O.
MM-HMM.
FOUR O's.
THIS IS GONNA BE CLOSE.
OKAY.
OOH.
N.
THREE N's.
BOY, THE MONEY'S
GEBIG HERE -- $10,800.
BUY A VOWEL,
SPIN THE WHEEL?
I'LL BUY A VOWEL -- U.
YES, ONE U.
YOU CAN BUY ANOTHER
IFTTING ANT.
I'LL BUY THE A.
MIGHT AS WELL, LAST ONE.
TWO A's.
S.
NO, NO S. SORRY.
OH.
ANTHONY, YOUR TURN.
ARONNA HEAR
THAT FAMOUS CHORD?
YES, WE ARE.
[ MYSTERY ROUND MUSIC PLAYS ]
WHAT LETTER
WOULD YOU LIKE, ANTHONY?
T.
THERE ARE FIVE T's,
WHICH MIGHT, UH, CHANGE YOUR,
UH, WHAT -- YOUR STRATEGY HERE,
BECAUSE THOSE T's
ARE WORTH $5,000.
I DON'T KNOW
WHETHER YOU'RE WILLING
TO RISK THAT AMOUNT
TOA LOOK,
BUT THERE'S A 50/50 CHANCE
OF $10,000 BACK THERE, ANTHONY.
BUT IT'S A $5,000 GAMBLE.
UH, I THINK I'LL SPIN AGAIN.
OKAY, I DON'T BLAME YOU.
TAKE THE $5,000, SPIN AGAIN.
GET OUT OF THERE.
C.
C YOU SAID?
UH-HUH.
THERE ARE THREE OF THEM.
SORRY.
$5,900.
C.
, THE MUSIC COMES AGAIN.
[ MYSTERY ROUND MUSIC PLAYS ]
H.
THERE ARE THREE H's.
IF YOU DIDN'T DO IT
FOR $5,000,
I DON'T THINK
YOU'RE GONNA DO IT FOR $8,900,
HAVE ANOTHER LOOK BACK THERE,
RIGHT?
NO. I'LL SPIN.
WE GOT TO GET HIM OUT OF THERE.
OKAY, A LETTER.
CAN I GET A G?
YES, ONE G. ALL RIGHT,
YOU'RE DOING FINE, ANTHONY.
PICK UP THAT WILD CARD. YOU GOT
THAT. YOU GOT A LOT OF MONEY.
WHAT DO YOU WANT TO DO NEXT?
IT'S SPIN OR SOLVE.
L.
UH-HUH.
THERE ARE TWO L's.
THAT'S ANOTHER $1,000.
YOU HAVE $9,900.
WHAT LETTER?
W.
THERE IS A W,
IN FACT, TWO OF THEM.
MAYBE THIS WILL DO IT.
$10,700.
IF YOU'RE PREPARED TO SOLVE IT,
GO AHEAD. IF NOT --
I'D LIKE TO SOLVE.
OKAY, GO AHEAD.
THROWING CAUTION
TO THE WIND-CHILL FACTOR.
THAT'S IT. [ LAUGHS ]
ABOUT YOU A,
I DON'T KNOW
ABOUT YOU ALL,
BUT I'M NOT GONNA MAKE IT
THROUGH THIS SHOW.
YOU'RE ALL JUST -- MAN.
BUT, UH, IT'S ALL WORKING OUT
FINE. LOOK AT THAT0,700.
YOU HAD A COUPLE OF "TOSS UPS"
EARLIER. $13,700.
HERE, HANG ON TO THAT.
THERE YOU GO.
AND WE'LL COME -- $1
TO PLAY SOME MORE "WHEEL."
IT'S KIND OF DRAMATIC
OUT HERE.
WHOO.
WE'LL SEE WHAT HAPPENS
IN A MINUTE. YOU HAD ME WORRIED.
[ LAUGHS ]
CLOSED CAPTIONING IS BROUGHT
TO YOU BY THE FOLLOWING...
Man: WHAT MOVES ME?
HEALTHY JOINTS.
AND NEW MOVE FREE.
IT HELPS MY BODY
MAINTAIN AND REPAIR
UP TO 38% MORE CARTILAGE.
HEALTHY JOINTS MOVE FREE.
"RHYME TIME" IS THE CATEGORY.
EVERYBODY'S READY,
AND OFF WE GO.
[ BELL CHIMES ]
JODY.
BACK ON TRACK.
YES, YOU ARE. SHE'S OVER0,000 N.
"FICTIONAL CHARACTERS-S-S-S,"
THAT'S THE CATEGORY.
[ BELL DINGS ]
AND TIME'S RUN
$3 A LITTLE SHORT,
SO I'LL GIVE THE WHEEL
A FINAL SPIN.
ASK YOU TO GIVE ME A LETTER.
IF IT'S IN THE PUZZLE, YOU'LL
HAVE THREE SECONDS TO SOLVE IT.
VOWELS WORTH NOTHING.
CONSONANTS -- WE'LL ADD $1,000.
NING
APIECE.
"FICTIONAL CHARACTERS,"
THE CATEGORY.
JODY, WE'LL START WITH YOU.
LET'S HAVE A LETTER.
T.
TWO T's.
ANY THOUGHTS,
FEEL$1,300EMOTIONS?
[ BUZZER ]
TAMMY.
N.
ONE N.
♪ LA DA DE
ER ]
ANTHONY.
D.
ONE D.
"FICTIONAL CHARACTERS."
A.
HANG ON,
ONE SECOND, JODY.
[ BUZZER ]
WHAT LETTER
WOULD YOU LIKE, JODY?
MAY I PLEASE HAVE
AN A? [ LAUGHS ]
YES, YOU MAY.
THREE A's.
NO MONEY FOR VOWELS,
BUT YOU'LL GET THREE SECONDS.
[ BUZZER ]
TAMMY.
TWO R's.
"FICTIONAL CHARACTERS."
[ BUZZER ]
ANTHONY.
E.
TWO E's.
[ LAUGHS ]
[ BUZZER ]
JODY.
S.
TWO S's.
COULD YOU MOVE
A LITTLE FASTER, VANNA?
THREE SECONDS.
B. OH, OH.
I CAN'T. I CAN'T.
[ BUZZER ]
SHH. [ LAUGHS ]
JUST HUSH. TAMMY.
P.
TWO P's.
PAPA SMURF AND SMURFETTE.
YEAH, THAT'S IT.
WHOO!
[ LAUGHS ]
HI.
WELL, I'M GLAD THAT
WORKED OUT FOR YOU.
FINALLY, YEAH.
YEAH. UH, YOU KNOW,
YOU ENDED UP WITH $6,500.
THAT'S A PRETTY GOOD HAUL.
THANKS, TAMMY,
VERY MUCH FOR BEING HERE.
NICE TO HAVE YOU ALONG.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
HE DID VERY WELL, TOO.
CONGRATULATIONS, ANTHONY.
NICE JOB. $13,700.
I HOPE THAT COMES IN HANDY.
YEAH.
IF YOU WEREN'T SO CUTE,
YOU'D BE GETTING ON MY NERVES.
[  ]
UH, $31,100 CASH AND PRIZES,
INCLUDING THE CAR,
THE TRIP TO THE CARIBBEAN.
IT'S GOING OKAY. WE'LL SEE
WHAT HAPPENS IN THE BONUS ROUND.
IT'LL PROBABLY BE INTERESTING.
SMILE AND WAVE.
HI VICTOR!
MOM?
I KNOW YOU GOT TO GO
IN A MINUTE
BUT THIS IS
A REAL QUICK MEAL,
THAT'S PERFECT FOR TWO!
CAMPBELL'S CHUNKY BEEF
WITH COUNTRY VEGETABLES,
POURED OVER RICE!
[ Male Announcer ]
CAMPBELL'S CHUNKY SOUP.
IT FILLS YOU UP RIGHT.
POURED OVER RICE!
of Washington about the future
of Medicare and Social Security.
ANNCR: But you deserve straight
talk about the options on the...
table and what they mean for you
and your family.
ANCR: AARP is cutting through
all the political spin.
Because for our 37 million
members, only one word counts.
Get the facts at earnedasay.org.
Let's keep Medicare...
and Social Security strong for
generations to come.
IT'S CREAMY, NONFAT, AND IT
TURNS THE NEXT PERSON YOU SEE
INTO JOHN STAMOS
FOR FIVE SECONDS.
HONEY! I THINK
I'M GETTINED! HEH!
EAT.
♪
TASTES PRETTY GOOD, HUH?
BEST YOGURT EVER.
YEAH!
[ men grunting ]
OPEN!
[ Male Announcer ]
DANNON OIKOS BERRY FLAVORS
BEAT CHOBANI 2 TO 1
IN A NATIONAL TASTE TEST.
OIKOS GREEK YOGURT.
POSSIBLY THE BEST YOGURT
IN THE WORLD.
YOU SPEND ALL DAY COOKING IT.
SO WHY SPEND EVEN A MOMENT
CONSIDERING ANY BROTH
BUT SWANSON?
THE BROTH COOKS TRUST MOST
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
IN STUAND MORE,
THE SECRET IS SWANSON.
THOUGH I DON'T THINK SHE'S
EVER ACTUALLY SEEN THE SHOW.
BUT YOU'RE HAVING A GOOD TIME,
RIGHT?
[ LAUGHS ] YES.
NO, YOU'RE DOING GREAT. WHO'S
OUT IN THE AUDIENCE WITH YOU?
MY MOM, SHIRLEY, MY COUSIN
KELLY, AND MY FRIEND DION.
ALL RIGHT,
GOOD TO SEE YOU ALL.
AND YOU READY
TO SPIN THE WHEEL?
I AM.
ALL RIGHT, GO AHEAD, JODY.
[ HUMMING ]
BOOM.
WOULD YOU GRAB THAT FOR ME?
THANK YOU.
PLEASE, COME WITH ME.
AND YOU'RE GONNA GO
RIGHT HERE.
NOW, THE CATEGORY TONIGHT
IS "PH
R, S, T, L, N, E,
VANNA.
VANNA LOOKS LIKE BRASE."D SPENT
TOO MUCH TIME IN THE SUN.
ALL RIGHT.
NOW, THAT'S ALL YOU'RE GONNA GET
IS THAT ONE LETTER.
WE NEED THREE MOREIG BIRNANTS
AND A VOWEL.
C.
THAT'S ONE.
H.
TWO.
P.
THAT WOULD BE THREE.
NOW WE NEED A VOWEL.
I.
ALL RIGHT.
[ BELL DINGING ]
A LOT OF DINGING GOING ON.
THAT'S GOOD.
WELL, LET'S SEE
HE CAN COME UP WITH THIS.
"PHRASE" IS THE CATEGORY.
YOU HAVE 10 SECONDS TO TALK
IT OUT, OKAY. GOOD LUCK.
A HAPPY REUNION.
NOPE.
NO? A HAPPY...
A HAPPY...
[ BUZZER ]
YEAH, NOT TOO BIG, NOT TOO
SMALL, JUST A HAPPY MEDIUM.
MEDIUM.
YEAH, I'M SORRY.
WELL, YOU GOT SOME OF IT.
BUT I DON'T KNOW.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO?
I HAVE TO LOOK IN HERE
AND SEE THAT.
WE COULDN'T ADD THAT
TO YOUR TOTAL.
BUT SHE WON MORE THAN THAT --
$31,100.
AND IT WAS A TON OF FUN.
THANK YOU, JODY, VERY MUCH.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH, PAT.
VANNA AND I
WILL BE RIGHT BACK,
AND I'LL -- I'LL DO A MAKE GOOD
ON THE DRESS REMARK.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU.
THE WHEELMOBILE
IS TOURING THE COUNTRY
LOOKING FOR CONTESTANTS.
IT COULD BE VISITING
YOUR TOWN SOON.
BROUGHT TO YOU
BY UnitedHealthcare.
SERVING MEDICARE BENEFICIARIES
FOR OVER 30 YEARS.
I WAS MAKING A LITTLE JOKE,
BUT IT'S QUITE LOVELY...
THANK YOU.
...AND IT'S A LOVELY COLOR.
THAT'S A LOT OF DRESS, THOUGH.
THERE'S -- IT IS.
THERE'S LAYERS AND LAYERS.
THERE'S THINGS.
YOU HAVE LAYERS.
SEE, THERE'S LAYERS AND LAYERS.
THAND LAYERS AND LAYERS.HOUGH.
THERE'S -- IT IS.     BOY, LOOK.
THERE'S A SMALL FAMILY
OF FERRETS LIVING UNDER THERE.
[ LAUGHS ]
BUT IT'S COMFORTABLE.
GOOD. IT'S VERY NICE.
THANK YOU.
UH, WE'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME
FOR MORE FASHION ADVICE
HERE ON "WHEEL OF FORTUNE."
BYE.
PROMOTIONAL CONSIDERATION
PROVIDED BY...
Announcer:
ITCHY, DRY SCALP?
GET SELSUN BLUE
FOR ITCHY, DRY SCALP.
STRONG ITCH-FIGHTERS
TARGET SCALP ITCH,
WHILE 5 MOISTURIZERS
LEAVE HAIR HEALTHY.
SELSUN BLUE.
GOT A CLUE? GET THE BLUE.
Woman: CH-CH-CH-CHIA!
Announcer: CHIA PETS,
THE POTTERY THAT GROWS!
AND NOW...
Children:
SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS!
Announcer:GEBOB.
AND EVERYONE'S FAVORITE GAL --
CHIA HELLO KITTY.
SPREAD THE SEEDS, WATER,
AND WATCH IT GROW.
Woman: CH-CH-CH-CHIA!
Announcer: THERE'S EVENA S.
SO MANY CHIA PETS,
YOU CAN COLLECT THEM ALL!
-- Captions by VITAC --
www.vitac.com
>> Woman: THE FOLLOWING IS A
PAID PRESENTATION FOR THE NUWAVE
PRECISION INDUCTION COOKTOP,
BROUGHT TO YOU BY THE MAKERS OF
THE NUMBER-ONE-SELLING
NUWAVE OVEN.
>> Announcer: WHEN YOU TURN ON
YOUR COOKTOP, DO YOU REALLY KNOW
WHAT THE TEMPERATURE IS?
NO-- YOU'RE JUST GUESSING.
ARE YOU TOO BUSY TO WATCH
WHAT YOU'RE COOKING?
TIRED OF ALL THAT BURNT FOOD
GOING TO WASTE?
WORRIED ABOUT YOUR KIDS GETTING
BURNED OR A LOVED ONE STARTING
A FIRE IN THE KITCHEN?
WELL, THOSE PROBLEMS ARE
A THING OF THE PAST.
INTRODUCING THE REVOLUTIONARY
PRECISION INDUCTION COOKTOP FROM
NUWAVE, THE LEADER IN PORTABLE
INDUCTION COOKING TECHNOLOGY.
THE NUWAVE HEATS UP TWICE AS
FAST