HERE ARE THE LATEST DEVELOPMENTS
THIS MORNING ON THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL VISIT NEW
TOWN THIS EVENING TO MEET WITH
THE FAMILIES AND ATTEND A VIGIL.
THEY WILL FAN OUT TO GUN STORES
AND SHOOTING RANGES ACROSS
CONNECTICUT LOOKING FOR CLUES
ABOUT THE 20-YEAR-OLD GUNMAN WHO
KILLED 26 CHILDREN AND ADULTS IN
FRIDAY'S RAMPAGE.
HE FORCED HIS WAY INTO THE
SCHOOL BREAKING A WINDOW AT THE
FRONT ENTRANCE.
HE SHOT AND KILLED A SCHOOL
PRINCIPAL AND SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST WHO RAN TOWARDS HIM
TOO TRY TO PROTECT THE CHILDREN.
SURVIVING TWINS DESCRIBE HOW
THEIR TEACHERS SAVE THEIR LIVES.
>>> WENT INTO MY TEACHER'S
OFFICE, EVERYONE WAS QUIET.
SHE SAVED A LIFE.
SHE CALLED HER HUSBAND AND HE
CALLED THE POLICE.
WHEN THE POLICEMAN CAME TO GET
US HE TOLD US TO CLOSE OUR EYES
LIKE ON THE PICTURE ON THE NEWS
DO THIS.
AND RUN.
>> JUST GO OUT.
>> THE MEDICAL EXAMINER TOLD
REPORTERS ALL OF THE YOUNG
VICTIMS HAD BEEN SHOT NUMEROUS
TIMES.
AS THIS TRAGEDY UNFOLDS STAY
WITH ABC 7 NEWS FOR CONTINUING
COVERAGE.
WE ARE GOING TO HEAR ABOUT SOME
OF THE HEROS WHO HELPED SAVE
LIVES.
LAURA ANTHONY FROM CONNECTICUT
LART TODAY ON ABC 7 NEWS.
>> RIGHT NOW IN THE BAY AREA IT
IS A SOGGY START TO SOUR SUNDAY.
WE HAVE A LOOK AT THE WEATHER.
>> WE ARE MILDER THAN YESTERDAY.
HI TEMPERATURE YESTERDAY WAS 49.
RIGHT NOW WE SIT AT 49.
LOW LEVEL MOISTURE KEEPING IT
MILD.
THEY ARE NOT WIDESPREAD FOCUSED
MAINLY ON THE NORTH BASE.
NUMBERS TO THE 40s AND NEAR 50
THIS MORNING.
BY THIS AFTERNOON ONCE AGAIN THE
NORTH BAY THE COASTAL HILLS
SAVER THE SHOWER ACTIVITY WITH
TEMPERATURES IN THE MID 50s.
ANOTHER SYSTEM IS ON THE WAY.
IT COULD BRING ANYWHERE FROM
HALF INCH TO AN INCH OF RAIN IN
THE WITTEST LOCATIONS IN THE
NORTH BAY.
THEY PICK UP OVER THE NEXT 12-18
HOURS OR SO.
THEY BRING STORMS TO THE PACIFIC
AND BRING US A RAINY COUPLE OF
DAYS IN AUTUMN.
>> THANK YOU LISA.
>> GRIEVING COMMUNITY CAME TO A
CANDLELIGHT VIGIL.
THEY SHARE STORIES OF LOSS SO
MANY FAMILIES ARE COPEING WITH.
A DOCTOR WHO HELPED VICTIMS IS
ALSO DEEPLY SHAKEN BY WHAT HE
EXPERIENCED.
>> THIS IS THE DARKEST THING I
HAVE EVER WALKED INTO BY FAR.
I HAVE BEEN THROUGH MEDICAL
TRAINING WHICH HAS TAUGHT ME A
LOT ABOUT DEALING WITH STRESSFUL
SITUATIONS AND THIS IS THE
DARKEST THING I HAVE EVER
EXPERIENCED IN MY LIFE.
VERY TRAUMATIC AND JUST
HORRIFIC.
>>> THERE WAS ALSO A CHURCH
SERVICE LAST NIGHT TO GIVE
PEOPLE A CHANCE FOR SPIRITUAL
HEALING.
PEOPLE REACH OUT TO SUPPORT ONE
ANOTHER.
PEOPLE WHO KNEW THE GUNMAN ADAM
LANZA IN HIGH SCHOOL DESCRIBE A
SHY INDIVIDUAL AN HONOR STUDENT
A MEMBER OF THE TECH CLUB.
HIS AUNT SAYS HE TALKED TO
LANZA'S MOM ABOUT HIS TROUBLES.
>> SHE WOUND UP HOME SCHOOLING
HIM SHE BATTLED WITH THE SCHOOL
NOT SURE IF IT WAS BEHAVIOR
LOR
LORNING DISABILITY.
HE ISSUED THIS STATEMENT OUR
HEARTS GO OUT TO THE FAMILY AND
FRIENDS WE, TOO, ARE ASKING WHY.
HEROS IN THE LINE OF FIRE.
>> SHE LOCKED THE DOOR AND TAPED
A PIECE OF WHITE TAPE OVER THE
DWOIN OF THE WSH WSH OVER THE
WINDOW OF THE DOOR.
SHE TOLD US TO GO IN THE CORNER.
THERE ARE 19 PEOPLE IN OUR
CLASS.
SHE SAVED ALL OF US.
>> THIRD GRADER TORI TRAP CAME
HOME SAFELY TO HER MOM THANKS TO
HER TEACHER'S RAPID RESPONSE.
>> THE UNITED WAY STARTED A
DONATION DRIVE FOR THE VICTIMS
OF THE SHOOTING.
WE HAVE A LINK TO THE WEB PAGE
AT ABC7NEWS.COM.
YOU CAN ALSO POST THIS BADGE TO
YOUR FACEBOOK WALL A SILENT SHOW
OF SUPPORT FOR EVERYONE IN NEW
TOWN CONNECTICUT AVAILABLE AT
FACEBOOK.COM SLASH ABC 7 NEWS.
>>> IN OTHER NEWS THIS MORNING
SAN FRANCISCO POLICE ARRIVED TO
AN ARGUMENT.
THEY BACKED AWAY BECAUSE THEY
THOUGHT THE MAN MIGHT HAVE A
WEAPON.
THEY WERE TOLD SHO SHELTER IN
PLACE UNTIL THE MANSUR RENDERED.
THEY WERE SEARCHING FOR A WEAPON
PAST MIDNIGHT.
>>> TWO ADULTS AND JUVENILE HAD
BEEN RAISED FOR THE SHOOTING
DEATHS IN OAKLAND.
14-YEAR-OLD RAQUEL AND
15-YEAR-OLD BOBBY WERE GUNNED
DOWN ON A QUIET STREET CORNER.
A CAR DROVE BY AND FIRED AT
LEAST 36 SHOTS.
>>> A 16-YEAR-OLD BOY WAS
ACCUSED OF PAINT BE BOMB
THREATS.
THIS GRAFFITI NAME ADD TEACHER
FROM MONTA VISTA HIGH.
WE HAVE OBSCURED HIS NAME TO
PROTECT HIS IDENTITY.
ALMOST IDENTICAL MESSAGES WERE
SPRAYED ON THE WALLS IN TWO
OTHER SCHOOLS IN THE AREA.
CLASSES WERE CANCELED AT MONTA
VISTA HEY AND NEIGHBORING
LINCOLN SCHOOL.
>>> A POSSIBLE POWER SHIFT IN
JAPAN ON ABC 7 NEWS THIS
MORNING.
>> ALSO IN THE EFFORT TO AVOID
THE FISCAL CLIFF THE
>> A CYCLONE THAT RAKED SIM MOW
YAW IS BARING DOWN ON FIJI.
THOUSANDSS ARE LEFT HOMELESS BY
SIGH CO
CYCLONE EVAN.
PEOPLE WHO SURVIVED A DEADLY
2009 TSUNAMI SAY THIS STORM IS
AN EVEN WORSE DISASTER.
TOURISTS ARE BACK LACKLOGGED AT
AIRPORTS IN NEW ZOE LAND.
>> -- NEW ZEALAND.
>> WE MAY GET PEOPLE IN THE
FRONT BUT THEY ARE PRIT TOOEFR
BOOKED.
>>> THEY ARE AMONG THE TOURISTS
WHO HAVE BEEN EVACUATEDD FROM
FIJI AND ARE CAMPED OUT TRYING
TO FIND A WAY HOME.
>>> ISLAMISTS ARE CLAIM AGO
MAJORITY VOTE ON THE COUNTRY'S
PROPOSED CHARTER.
THE MUSLIM BROTHERHOOD SAYS IT
HAS A NARROW MAJORITY IN THE
FIRST ROUND ON THE PROPOSED
ISLAMIST BACKED CONSTITUTION.
THE BROTHERHOOD'S OWN COUNT SAYS
50 PERCENT OF THE 26 MILLION
VOTERS APPROVE THE DISPUTED
CHARTER.
MORE VOTING SET TO TAKE PLACE
FOR THE COUNTRY'S REMAINING 25
MILLION VOTERS.
EGYPTIAN PRESIDENT MOHAMMED
MORSI HAILS FROM THE GROUP THAT
ACCURATELY PREDICTED PAST
ELECTION RESULTS.
JAPANESE VOTERS ARE VOTING IN A
GENERAL ELECTION THAT WILL GIVE
THE COUNTRY IT'S 7TH PRIME
MINISTER IN 6 YEARS.
EARLY POLLS SUGGEST MOST VOTERS
WILL BACK THE LIBERAL DEMOCRATIC
PARTY GIVING IT ANOTHER CHANCE
THREE YEARS AFTER VOTERS OUSTED
THEM.
TSUNAMI POLITICS MAY PLAY A ROLE
MORE THAN A YEAR AFTER THE
DISASTER.
THOUSANDS ARE SUFFERING THROUGH
A SECOND WINTER WAITING FOR
THEIR HOMES TO BE REBUILT.
AS LAWMAKERS HERE AND THE
PRESIDENT GRAPPLE WITH WAYS TO
AVOID THE IMPENDING FISCAL CLIFF
A TOP REPUBLICAN OFFERED TO
RAISE INCOME TAXES ON AMERICANS
EARNING MORE THAN $1 MILLION A
YEAR.
>>> THE MOVE BY HOUSE SPEAKER
JOHN BOEHNER AS A CONCESSION IN
NEGOTIATIONS WITH PRESIDENT
OBAMA TO AVOID THE FAST
APPROACHING END OF TEMPORARY TAX
CUTS.
BUT THE OFFER FALLS FAR SHORT OF
THE PRESIDENT'S DEMAND FOR AN
INCREASE ON HOUSEHOLD EARNINGS
MORE THAN 250,000 DOLLARS.
WHILE THE NEWS SUGGESTS A
POSSIBLE BREAK THROUGH IN THE
STAND OFF
STANDOFF TO REDUCE THE MAY GOS'S
HUGE DEBT PROBLEM A SPOKESMAN
FOR BOEHNER SAYS A DEAL IS NOT
EMINENT.
>>> THERE ARE SO MANY LIRNGING
QUESTIONS FROM FRIDAY'S SCHOOL
SHOOTING IN CONNECTICUT ABC THIS
WEEK HAS ASSEMBLED A TEAM OF
POLITICAL LEADERS IN CONNECTICUT
TO TRY TO ANSWER THEM.
CAN ANY MEASURES PROTECT FROM
MASS SHOOTINGS IN THE FUTURE?
HOW WILL OFFICIALS RESPOND?
THE SENATORS JOIN GEORGE
STEPHANOPOLIS COMING UP.
DON'T MISS THIS SPECIAL EDITION
OF THIS WEEK WITH GEORGE THIS
MORNING AT 8:00 RIGHT HERE ON
ABC 7.
>>> IS THE ENTIRE WEEKEND GOING
TO BE A WASHOUT IN YOU HAVE YOUR
EYE ON LIVE DOPPLER 7 HD.
>> NOT EVERY WHERE.
WE HAVE A BIT OF A BREAK OUT
THERE. LIGHT SHOWERS WE WILL BE
FAVORING THE COAST FROM NORTH
BAY.
LIVE LOOK OUTSIDE FROM THE ROOF
CAMERA YOU WILL NOTICE NICE AND
MILD 49 DEGREES RIGHT NOW.
WARMER THAN IT WAS ALL DAY
YESTERDAY IN THE CITY.
WE WILL TALK ABOUT THE RAIN
COMING IN TONIGHT AND BUSY WEEK
AHEAD.
>> YOU WILL GET A PIECE OF THE
WORLD SERIES CHAMPIONS.
IF YOU ARE LOOKING FOR A HOLIDAY
GIFT FOR A BASEBALL FAN YOU
DON'T WANT TO
>> THANKS FOR WAKING UP AS AN
EARLY BIRD.
JOINING THE ABC 7 SUNDAY MORNING
NEWS.
THIS IS A LIVE LOOK AT THE
GOLDEN GATE BRIDGE.
MOST OF THEM HUDDLING IN THE BED
WITH ALL OF THE BLANKETS PULLED
UPTIGHT.
IT HAS BEEN SO COLD AROUND HERE
IN THE LAST FEW DAYS.
LISA WILL BE ALONG WITH THE FULL
ACCU-WEATHER FORECAST.
>> THIS AFTERNOON VOLUNTEERS
WILL SORT THROUGH DONATED TOYS
FOR NEXT SATURDAY'S BIG TOY
DISTRIBUTION.
YOU CAN SEE FROM THIS VIDEO IT
BRINGS MAGIC TO THE EYES OF SOME
LOCAL CHILDREN WHO MIGHT NOT
OTHERWISE HAVE A HAPPY HOLIDAY.
VOLUNTEERS WILL MEET AT 2:00 AT
GOFF AND GARY STREET IN SAN
FRANCISCO.
LISA ARGIN HERE NOW WITH THE
FULL CHECK OF THE ACCU-WEATHER
FORECAST.
>> IT HAS BEEN SO COLD BECAUSE
WE HAVE HAD THE CLEAR SKY WITH
AMPLE CLOUD COVER.
DID YOU NOTICE THE CHANGE THIS
MORNING?
>> NO.
>> IT HAS BEEN VERY COLD.
AS YOU HEAD OUT THIS MORNING YOU
WILL NOTICE IT.
THIS IS OUR SUTRO CAMERA.
4:52 GIVING US 9 HOURS 43
MINUTES OF DAYLIGHT.
NOT PICKING MUCH UP WE ARE
LOOKING AT A FEW SPRINKLES ALONG
THE COAST.
THE FOCUS OF THE RAIN WILL BE IN
THE NORTH BAY.
WE WILL GET TO THAT THAT AND
SHOW YOU NOT MUCH IS GOING ON.
THINGS GETTING MORE ACTIVE AS
THE PACIFIC STORM COMES OUR WAY.
SHOWERS MIDDAY.
LESSER AMOUNTS TO THE SOUTH.
49 IN SAN FRANCISCO.
GOOD MORNING OAKLAND 47 FOR YOU.
REAL KWLIFR ONE ELSE IN THE LOW
TO MID 40s.
SO BIG CHANGE THIS MORNING WITH
UPPER 40s HALF-MOON BAY.
HOW MUCH WARMER THAN YESTERDAY?
I HAVE THOSE FOR YOU ANYWHERE
FROM 12-15 DEGREES WARMER.
CERTAINLY NOT AS COLD WITH A FEW
LIGHT SHOWERS PERHAPS.
TODAY SHOWERS WILL BE ALONG THE
COASTAL HILLS THE NORTH BAY.
WE COULD SEE ONE POP-UP
ANYWHERE.
WE WILL LOOK FOR MORE
CONCENTRATED RAIN TONIGHT ABOUT
10:00 TONIGHT.
THAT'S IN ADVANCE OF THIS NEXT
STORM SYSTEM.
RIGHT NOW WE ARE IN THE WARM
SECTOR.
YOU CAN SEE ALL OF THE CLOUD
COVER HERE.
A LITTLE BIT MORE RAIN UP TO THE
NORTH.
WE HAVE LIGHT SNOW BEING
REPORTED IN SIERRA, NEVADA RIGHT
NOW.
THROUGH OUT THE NEXT 12-18 HOURS
OR SO CLOUDY SKIES WITH A SNURS.
TO T
-- WITH A FEW SHOWERS.
WE LUWILL BE LOOKING AT HEAVIER
RAIN THAT WILL ALLOW HALF AN
INCH TO AN INCH OF RAIN.
LIGHT SHOWER ACTIVITY FROM THE
NORTH BAY.
MORE CONCENTRATED FROM SAN
FRANCISCO.
AL FEW BREAKS BUT BY ABOUT 9,
10:00 TONIGHT YOU CAN SEE THE
HEYER RAIN FROM SAN RAF FELL UP
THROUGH NAPA ON THROUGH THE
OVERNIGHT HOURS.
HERE WE ARE MONDAY MORNING.
BY ABOUT MIDDAY TOMORROW THAT'S
WHEN WE SEE THINGS CLEAR OUT.
WE WILL GET INTO A NICE BREAK
THE REST OF MONDAY INTO TUESDAY.
A FEW ISOLATED SHOWERS.
EVEN WEDNESDAY LOOKS TO BE THE
DRIEST DAY AROUND HERE.
THEN THINGS WILL BE GETTING
QUITE INTERESTING BY THE END OF
THE WORKWEEK INTO THE NEXT
WEEKEND.
SO WE HAVE TO LOOK FOR SOME BIG
CHANGES THEN.
BUT IN THE MEANTIME JUST A FEW
LIGHT SHOWERS ALONG THE COAST.
OUR NEXT SYSTEM COMING IN
TONIGHT 54 SAN JOSE.
IN BETWEEN SYSTEMS WITH A LITTLE
MORE SUNSHINE AS YOU HEAD
FURTHER SOUTH IN SAN JOSE AND
THE CENTRAL COAST.
THE RAIN OVERNIGHT INTO MONDAY
THE BREAK TUESDAY WEDNESDAY AND
HEYER RAIN WINTER RIVES ON
FRIDAY.
THAT LAST WEEKEND BEFORE
CHRISTMAS BUSY, BUSY LOOKING
WET.
>> WOW.
THANK YOU, LISA.
HERE IS YOUR CHANCE TO GET YOUR
HANDS ON SOME MEMORABILIA FROM
THE WORLD CHAMPION SAN FRANCISCO
GIANTS.
AT NOON TODAY ITEMS USED OR WORN
BY TEAM PLAYERS THIS PAST SEASON
WILL GO ON SALE AT AT&T PARK.
A PORTION OF THE PROCEED RAISED
WILL GO TOWARD THE GIANT'S
COMMUNITY FUND.
THIS WILL BE YOUR CHANCE TO BUY
A FUTURE COLLECTABLE.
IN SPORTS TODAY THE 49ERS
PREPARE TO FACE TOM BRADY AND
NEW ENGLAND CHAMPIONS.
WHILE STATE CHAMPIONS EMERGE IN
HIGH SCHOOL TOFOOTBALL.
THE WARRIORS WITH THE BEST START
IN MANY, MANY YEARS.
>> GOOD MORNING.
THE LONGEST ROAD TRIP OF THE
YEAR 7 GAMES IN 11 DAYS END
YESTERDAY IN ATLANTA.
THEY WON THE FIRST FIVE WHICH
INCLUDED A WIN OVER THE MIAMI
HEAT TOOK A LOSS IN ORLANDO BUT
WON IN ATLANTA.
ROOKIE HARRISON BARNS IMPROVING
EVERY GAME.
3 OF HIS 12 IN THE FIRST HALF.
HE HAD 19 IN THE GAME.
KARL LANDRIEU ONE HAND SLAM.
HE HAD 19 AS WELL.
62 WERE 49 WARRIORS AT THE HALF.
THIS TEAM IS MOST EFFECTIVE WHEN
EVERYONE GETS INVOLVED.
DAVID LEE 20 POINTS AVERAGING A
DOUBLE DOUBLE.
20-10 EVERY SINGLE GAME ON THIS
TRIP.
HEALTH CURIE PLAYING LIKE AN ALL
STAR.
A LITTLE STEEL AND SLAM HERE.
HE HAD 18 POINTS.
WARRIORS 6-1 ON A ROAD TRIP FOR
THE FIRST TIME IN FRANCHISE
HISTORY.
150-93 THAT FINAL.
NONCONFERENCE MATCH UP AFTER A
COUPLE WEEKS OF EXAMS.
ONLY PLAYER TO SHOW UP 23 OF THE
TEAM'S 52 POINTS.
RUSH NEVER SLEEPS.
THE JUMPER AND THE FOUL.
HE HAD 14 POINTS.
CARDINALS LED 14-29 AT THE HALF.
7-3 WITH A 75-52 VICTORY.
>>> 26 POINTS IN THE FIRST HALF.
COBBS CARRIED THE LOAD AT 18.
10 OF 17 FROM THE FIELD.
34 POINTS.
MONSTER GAME FOR THE BLUE JAYS.
THEY FALL TO 6-3.
>>> FACING TORONTO CENTENNIAL
FOR THE OPEN DIVISION CROWN.
THEY HAVE THE LEADING OFFENSE
WITH TWO 1,000 YARD RUSHERS.
BOB LAD KERR TALKED ABOUT
RETIRING AFTER 34 YEARS AT THE
HELM.
THREE OF HIS FOUR RUSHING
TOUCHDOWNS IN THE FIRST HALF.
THIS FOR 46 YARDS.
QUARTERBACK CHRIS WILLIAMS GUNS
IT TO AUSTIN LONE STAR.
GREAT NAME.
CENTENNIAL HAS A GREAT OFFENSE
BUT COULDN'T GET ANY CLOSER THAN
14.
EXTENDING THE LEAD ONCE AGAIN.
DE LASS SAL DIVISION CHAMPIONS
FOR THE 4TH STRAIGHT YEAR 48-28
THE FINAL.
CATHOLIC AND MADISON MC
QUARTERBACK HEADED TO CAL
THROUGH 4 TD'S THIS ONE TO HAND
LEE.
WILDCATS UP 35-31.
MADISON ANSWERS ON THE ENSUING
DRIVE.
RAN FOR 272 YARDS.
YOU CAN'T COACH SPEED AND THIS
GUY HAS SOME.
DIVISION 3 CHAMPIONS 38-35
VICTORY.
>>> 49ERS IN NEW ENGLAND TAKING
ON THE PATRIOTS TONIGHT.
I AM MIKE SHUMANN.
HAVE A GREAT DAY.
>>> A CALIFORNIA MALL ON LOCK
DOWN.
AHEAD CAUSE FOR ALARM.
A BOMB SCARE AS BULLETS FLY.
AN UP SCALE FALL MALL IN SOUTHE
CALIFORNIA.
AHEAD THIS HOLIDAY SEASON A
TEXAS BUSINESS IS OFFERING A
DIFFERENT KIND OF SANTA
AND...
TAKE CARE OF THEM,
YOU KNOW?
I FEEL LIKE WE'VE
COME FULL CIRCLE.
LIKE THAT!
THIS IS HOW
I'LL DO IT.
Sarah:
THERE YOU GO.
NESPRESSO.
WHERE I NEVER HAVE TO COMPROMISE
ON ANYTHING.
♪
WHERE JUST ONE TOUCH
CREATES THE PERFECT COFFEE.
WHERE EVERY CAPPUCCINO AND LATTE
IS ONLY MADE WITH FRESH MILK.
AND WHERE THE STAFF
IS EXCEPTIONALLY FRIENDLY.
NESPRESSO. WHAT ELSE?
>> A PREVIOUSLY SCHEDULED GUN
BUY BACK PROGRAM GOT A BOOST
AFTER THE CONNECTICUT SHOOTING.
HUNDREDS WERE BOUGHT BACK BY
POLICE.
WE HAVE THE STORY.
>> I DECIDE TO DO GIVE UP MY
GUNS.
I DIDN'T NEED THEM.
>> MICHELLE WAS MORE THAN 200
PEOPLE WILLING TO SELL THEIR
GUNS TO AN FRAN POLICE.
HE WAS BROUGHT HERE BY THE SAME
TRAGEDY THE MASS MURDERER OF 20
CHILDREN IN CONNECTICUT.
>> HIT ME PRETTY STRONG.
I NEVER THOUGHT ABOUT GETTING
RID OF THEM BEFORE.
>> HE AND HIS WIFE SOBBED WHILE
TAKING IN THE NEWS.
>> I FEEL IF THIS IS SOMETHING
THAT MIGHT HURT SOMEBODY SOME
DAY, THEN I WOULD FEEL TERRIBLE
ABOUT THAT.
>> THE GUN BUY BACK WAS FUNDED
BY THE UP PRIZING PROGRAM IN
OAKLAND.
THEY CONTACTED THE OMEGA BOYS
CLUB IN SAN FRANCISCO.
JOEFS MARSHALL SAYS THE TURNOUT
SHOWS BOTH COMMUNITIES CARE
ABOUT GUN VIOLENCE.
>> WHEN THEY SAY ENOUGH IS
ENOUGH THEY HAVE A GOOD CHANCE.
>> THE TURN IN GUNS AT SAINT
BENEDICT ACE CHURCH.
THIS IS WHERE OAKLAND POLICE
WERE BUYING THE GUNS.
>> WE HAVE EVERY ANTICIPATION
THEY WILL BE EXCEEDING THE
WILDEST EXPECTATIONS.
>> $200 WERE FOUND FOR EACH HAND
GUN AND RIFLE.
PEOPLE HAD TO PROVE THEY WERE
RESIDING IN THE CITY BUYING THE
GUNS.
OAKLAND POLICE DEPARTMENTS ARE
GOING TO BE ASKING THE GOVERNOR
TO MAKE THE GUN BUY BACK A STATE
PROGRAM.
>> HERE IN THE BAY AREA THERE
ARE VIGILS AND MEMORIAL SERVICES
TO REMEMBER THE VICTIMS OF THE
CONNECTICUT OH TAKE A LISTEN.
>> WHAT YOU HEARD WAS LAST NIGHT
AT GRACE CATHEDRAL.
IT WAS DEDICATED TO THE INNOCENT
VICTIMS OF THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL SHOOTING SO WAS THE
ENTIRE HOLIDAY CONCERT THAT WENT
ON LAST NIGHT.
KONG GANTS COULDN'T HELP BUT
THINK OF THE 27 LIVES TAKEN.
>> THE BEAUTY OF THEM ECHOS AND
MAKES YOU THINK ABOUT THE LIFE
AS YOU SAID IS VERY PRECIOUS AND
THINGS YOU NEED DO TO TAKE CARE
OF YOUR LOVE WITHEDED ONES.
THEY WERE TRYING TO FIND LIGHT
IN THE DARK TIME.
THEY WILL BE DEDICATE TO DO THE
MEMORY OF THOSE KILLED.
THEY WOULD BE DEDICATED TO THE
VICTIMS AS WELL.
>> CONNECTICUT SCHOOL TRAGEDY
STIRRING UP THE GUN DEBATE
ACROSS THE NATION.
WH
ONE TEXAS GUN RANGE IS SMACK IN
THE MIDDLE AFTER OFFERING AN
UNUSUAL OPPORTUNITY WITH SANTA.
>> YOU GUYS COME ON.
>> IT'S CHRISTMAS.
>> HERE AT THE GUN RANGE THAT
MEANS PICTURES WITH SANTA.
AS AR 15 THEY SAY IT'S A CHILD
FRIENDLY EVENT.
>> I THINK IT'S EXTREMELY
IMPORTANT TO TRAIN PEOPLE TO
EDUCATE THEM.
>> DON'T TELL THAT TO PEERT
JOHNSON A STRONG ADVOCATE TO
KIDS AND GUNS CONTROL.
HE SAYS KIDS AND GUNS SENDS A
STRONG ME
THE WRONG MESSAGE.
>> WE HAVE TO TALK ABOUT OUR
LOVE AFFAIR WITH VIOLENCE.
>> VIOLENCE IN AMERICA WOULD
DECREASE IF IT WAS HARDER TO GET
WEAPONS.
HE TOOK THOUSANDS DURING GUN BUY
BACKSES.
>> WE WON'T BE ABLE TO TAKE GUNS
OUT OF AMERICA'S HANDS BUT WE
MUST TALK TO AMERICA ABOUT
VIOLENCE ITSELF.
>> THE OWNERS DON'T ADVOCATE
VIOLENCE.
THEY HAVE NUMEROUS GUN SAFETY
CLASSES.
>> THIS IS WON THE REASONS WE
OPENED THE RANGE WAS TO EDUCATE
CHILDREN, TO TRAIN THEM IN THE
CORRECT WAY TO USE THEM.
IT CAN BE A FUN SUPPORT.
IT DOESN'T HAVE TO BE A
DANGEROUS SUPPORT.
>> GUN RIGHTS ADVOCATES SAY THE
PROBLEM IS THE PERSON BEHIND THE
GUN NOT THE WEAPON ITSELF.
>> IF PEOPLE WANT TO HURT
ANOTHER PERSON THEY CAN USE A
BASEBALL BAT.
>> THE DIFFERENCE FOR BASEBALL
BAT IS FOR BASEBALL.
GUNS ARE FOR KILLING PEOPLE.
>> THEY ARE UNITE IFFED PAIN --
UNITED IN PAIN AND ANGER FOR THE
CONNECTICUT SHOOTING.
SOMETHING NEEDS TO BE DONE SO NO
MORE CHILDREN DIE IN SCHOOL.
>>> POLICE IN ORANGE COUNTY
FIRED ABOUT 50 SHOTS IN A
PARKING LOT IN AN UP SKATE NEW
PORT BEACH SHOPPING MALL.
SOMEONE CAPTURED THE GUN FIRE ON
HOME VIDEO.
>> NO ONE WAS INJURED AND POLICE
RAISED A 42-YEAR-OLD MAN WHILE
AN OUTDOOR MALL WENT INTO LOCK
DOWN.
IT IS NOT CLEAR WHY HE WAS
SHOOTING HIS GUN IN THE AIR BUT
POLICE REACTED QUICKLY IN THE
WAKE OF THE CONNECTICUT SCHOOL
TRAGEDY.
>>> YOU MAY HAVE HEARD ABOUT
GOVERNOR JERRY BROWN'S NIXING OF
THE CONTRACT IT IS A RENEWAL OF
THE PRICEY DEAL.
THE CHRONICLE REPORTS OVER THE
LAST FOUR YEARS THEY SPENT
$8 MILLION ON PUBLIC RELATIONS
MUCH OF IT GOING TO THE SAME
CONSULTANTS.
THE COMMUNICATIONS TEAM WAS
BILLING THE STATE AT RATES
TOPPING OUT AT $160 AN HOUR FOR
EACH MEMBER.
THEY PUT TOGETHER TWO WEB SITES
AND CONDUCTED MEDIA TOURS OF THE
NEW PBAY BRIDGE PROJECT.
THEY WANT TO BUILD A NEW JOB
CENTER BUT THE PLAN TO PAY FOR
IT IS A SELLOUT FOR THE
COMMUNITY.
THAT IS BECAUSE THE MONEY WOULD
COME FROM REVENUES GENERATED BY
A BILLBOARD ANOTHER THE TOLL
PLAZA.
>> TIME RIGHT NOW IS 5:34 THE
FOUNDER OF DOMINO'S PIZZA.
THEY ARE LOOKING AT MANDATORY
CONTRACEPTION COVERAGE AS A NEW
HEPT CARE LAW.
HE SAYS CONTRACEPTION IS A QUOTE
BRAVELY IMMORAL PRACTICE.
DOMINO'S PIZZA OFFERS HEALTH
INSURANCE THAT EXCLUDES
CONTRACEPTION AND APPORTIONS FOR
ITS EMPLOYEES.
THE NEW FEDERAL HEALTH LAW
REQUIRES EMPLOYERS TO OFFER
INSURANCE THAT INCLUDES
CONTRACEPTION OR RISK FINES.
SO MONAHAN IS WANTING A JUDGE TO
STRIKE DOWN THAT MANDATE.
>> IF YOU HAVE TROUBLE CATCHING
A CAB NOW WE HAVE AN APP FOR
THAT.
>> THEY SAY THEY STEEL THEIR
BUSINESS BY STARTING THEIR OWN.
>> HERE'S A LIVE LOOK FROM OUR
EAST BAY CAM.
IT WILL BE IN THE LOW 50s ACROSS
THE EAST BAY TODAY.
OUR METEOROLOGIST LISA ARGON
WILL HAVE YOUR FULL ACCU-WEATHEE
IT'S FINALLY HERE!
[ Woman #2 ]
IT'S THE REAL DEAL!
[ Man #1 ]
TURN IT AROUND! TURN IT AROUND!
[ Woman #1 ]
OVER HERE! OVER HERE!
[ Woman #2 ]
TURN AROUND! TURN AROUND!
[ Woman #1 ]
I LOVE YOU!
I CAN'T BELIEVE
IT'S NOT BUTTER!
NEITHER CAN I.
TURN THE TUB AROUND!
SHOW US THE BACK!
[ Man #1 ]
TURN THE TUB AROUND!
[ Female Announcer ]
WITH ZERO GRAMS
OF TRANS FAT PER SERVING,
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT'S NOT BUTTER
IS A SUPERSTAR!
♪
TURN THE TUB AROUND,
AND BECOME A BELIEVER.
WHILE WHILE THE OTHER APPS ARE
BUTTING HEADS WITH REGULATED
TORS THIS ONE IS WORKING WITH
THEM.
>> AS HE DRIVES HIS TAXI THROUGH
THE BUMPY STREETS IN SAN SAN'A
SMART BONE BELOW THE MEERT
STARTS TO BRING.
IT IS A BRAND NEW APP CALLED
FLYWHEEL.
IF YOU ARE A CUSTOMER THE APP
LOOKS LIKE THIS.
THEY ARE PARTICIPATING CABS IN I
ST.>> THE TECHNOLOGY HAS BEEN
AROUND FOR TWO YEARS SOME WERE
USING IT EVEN BEFORE HE BUNCHED
THE APP.
BACK THEN IT WAS CALLED TAB
LOUSE.
WITH THE DRIVE OFF IT IS BEING
REBORN AS FLY WHEELS WITH A
PROMISE TO HELP CABBIES COMPLETE
THE CARS AND DRIVERS WITH THE
MUSTACHES.
THEY GET MORE RIDES TODAY>> IT
IS IN A THIRD THEY CAN REPLACE
OR WORK ALONG SIDE THE TWO-WAY
RADIO TO GIVE DISPATCHERS A
BIRD'S-EYE VIEW OF WHERE ALL THE
DRIVERS ARE.
>> BY WORKING WITH DISPATCHERS
STIND OF GOING AROUND THEM
FLYWHEEL MANAGED TO GET BROAD
SUPPORT FROM CAB COMPANIES.
>> THREE OF THEM HAVE BEEN
ASSIGNED.
>> THEY BATTLE FINES FROM
REGULATORS THEY HAVE A GLOWING
ENDORSEMENT FROM THE CITY.
THIS IS SOMETHING WE WOULD
RECOMMEND.
>> IT PLANS TO HAIL ANY CAB IN
THE CITY.
JONATHAN BLOOM ABC 7 NEWS.
>>> APPLE IS UNVEILING IT'S LIST
OF BEST APPS NAND GAMES FOR I
PADS AND iPHONES IN 2012.
BAD ROBOT LED IN THE iPHONE
CATEGORY.
THE FREE APP ALLOWS USERS TO ADD
ACTION SEQUENCES TO VIDEOS SHOT.
IT IS THE TOP APP FOR THE iPAD
THE FREE DRAWING APPLICATION
CREATING A SKETCH BOOK OUT OF AN
iPAD.
BROOKLYN WANT TO GO BUILD A NEW
JOB CENTER THE PLAN TO PAY FOR
IT IS NOT GOOD.
THE MONEY WOULD COME WITH
REVENUES GENERATED BY A
BILLBOARD.
ABC 7 NEWS REPORTER LAURA
ANTHONY.
HOW TO PAY FOR A NEW JOB IN
CAREER RESOURCE CENTER IN WEST
OAKLAND.
A PROPOSED DEAL BETWEEN THE CITY
AND OAKLAND ARMY BASED DEVELOPER
WOULD FUND THE CENTER FROM
PROCEED WITH FIVE BRIGHT AND
SHINY BILLBOARDS AT THE BAY
BRIDGE LANDING.
>> THOSE DECISIONS HAVE BEEN
MADE AND NEGOTIATED SINCE THE
BILLBOARDS ARE GOING TO BE
THERE.
THE REVENUE OR SOME OF THE
REVENUE FROM THE BILLBOARD OUGHT
TO FUND THE JOB CENTER.
>>> AS A SHOW OF SUPPORT THEY
HELD A CANDLELIGHT VIGIL AND
PRAYER SERVICE.
THE EVENT WAS HELD ON 18TH AND
ADELINE WHICH WOULD HOUSE THE
CAREER CENTER.
IT IS ULTIMATELY A BAD ONE FOR
THE COMMUNITY.
>> WE ALL WANT JOBS AND A JOB
CENTER.
TO BASE IT ON POLL LAWSUITING
OUR LANDSCAPE THAT'S THE
TRADEOFF IT IS TRYING TO PIT US
GEEVENS OTHER WHICH IS THAT IS
THE INTENTION OF THIS.
>> WEST OAKLAND HAS ONE JOB
TRAINING CENTER THAT HAS PROVE
ENSUCCESSFUL OVER THE LAST
20-YEARS.
IT HELPED THE MOST TROUBLED
YOUNG PEOPLE TURN THEIR LIVES
AROUND WITH SKILLS AND JOB
PLACEMENT.
ART SHANK SAYS THE ENDS DO
JUSTIFY THE MEANS WITH A CENTER
IN THE AREA PLAGUED BY CRIME AND
UNEMPLOYMENT.
>> THINGS ARE TIGHT RIGHT NOW.
BILLBOARDS DEFINITELY WILL HELP
THE PROGRAM DEIT WILL BE A PLUS
PLUS.
>> WE ARE TALKING ABOUT ALL OF
THOSE APPS FOR iPHONES AND ALL
THAT.
>> WE HAVE A WEATHER APP.
>> AND THE REAL THING EVERY NOW
AND THEN.
>> WE ARE LOOKING AT MILD
CONDITIONS COMPARED TO
YESTERDAY.
SO MAYBE A FEW SHOWERS OUT
THERE.
BUT OVERALL A LITTLE BIT OF A
BREAK TODAY FOR THE MOST PART
BECAUSE THEIR NEXT SIGNIFICANT
WEATHER SYSTEM SEMI SIGNIFICANT
COMES IN TONIGHT.
WE HAVE AN ACTIVE WEEK AHEAD.
A GIFT OF THE
[ Boy 1 ] Hey!
That's the last Crescent.
Oh, did you want it?
Yea
We'll split it.
[ Female Announcer ]
Made fresh, so light,
buttery and flakey.
That's half
That's not half!
Guys, I have more!
Thanks Mom
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Crescents.
Let the Making Begin
[ Female Announcer ]
HOLIDAY COOKIES ARE A BIG JOB.
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE
JUST RIGHT.
PERFECTION IS IN THE DETAILS.
♪
GET TO HOLIDAY FUN FASTER
WITH PILLSBURY COOKIE DOUGH.
♪ OVER THE RIVER
AND DOWN THE ROAD ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
AT NATURE VALLEY,
WE KNOW NATURE COMES TOGETHER
IN AMAZING WAYS.
THAT'S WHY WE BRING TOGETHER
NATURAL INGREDIENTS,
LIKE DARK CHOCOLATE
WITH TOASTED OATS,
OR SWEET GOLDEN HONEY.
PERFECT COMBINATIONS OF
NATURE'S DELICIOUS INGREDIENTS,
FROM NATURE VALLEY.
♪
♪ I WAS THINKING
THAT I HOPE THIS NEVER ENDS ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA BARS,
NATURE AT ITS MOST DELICIOUS.
>> YOU SEE THE BUILDING IN THE
BACK LIT UP FOR THE HOLIDAY
SEASON.
IT HAS REALLY BEEN COLD AT NIGHT
AND RAINY, TOO.
OUR METEOROLOGIST LISA ARGIN
WILL BE ALONG TO TELL US IF THAT
IS GOING TO CHANGE ANY TIME
SOON.
>> A MILLION DOLLAR SCHOLARSHIP
FUND ESTABLISHED AT UC BURKE LEE
IS GOING TO HAVE AN AID TO THE
STUDENTS.
YOU CAN IMAGE IT IS NOT WITHOUT
CONTROVERSY.
ABC 7 NEWS LEEANN MELINN DEAD
HAS THE STORY.
>> HE WAS THE ONLY STUDENT AT
HIS HIGH SCHOOL TO GET INTO UC
BERKELEY.
>> I WAS LIKE YEAH, I GOT IN.
I WON'T BE ABLE TO GO.
>> HOW AM I GOING TO PAY FOR IT.
>> IT IS AN UNDOCUMENTED STUDENT
AND DOES NOT QUALIFY NR ANY
FEDERAL MONEY.
>> THE FEDERAL PELL GRANT WORK
STUDIES LOANS AREN'T ELIGIBLE TO
DOCUMENT STUDENTS.
>> THEY HAD A PRIVATE
SCHOLARSHIP HELPED PUT HIMSELF
THROUGH CAL.
IT WASN'T ENOUGH MONEY TO MAKE
ENDS MEET.
THAT'S HOW THEY HELPED STUDENTS
LIKE HIM.
WALTER HAST JUNIOR FUND
RESPONDED TO A ONE-MILLION
DOLLAR REWARD.
IT IS ABOUT EQUAL CHANCES EQUAL
TUNITIES LEVELING THE PLAYING
FIELD SO EVERYBODY HAS A CHANCE
TO SUCCEED IN LIFE.
>> ABOUT 200 UNDOCUMENTED
STUDENTS FROM UC BERKELEY WILL
RECEIVE A PORTION OF PRIVATE
MONEY BEGINNING IN THE SPRING.
EACH WILL RECEIVE ABOUT 5,000
DOLLARS.
IN 2011 THE CALIFORNIA
LEGISLATURE PASSED A BILL THAT
WILL GIVE UNDOCUMENTED STUDENTS
ACCESS TO STATE GRANTS STARTING
NEXT FALL.
ASSEMBLY BILL 131 HAS ALWAYS
BEEN CONTROVERSIAL.
EAST BAY PROFESSOR COAUTHORED
PROPOSITION 209 WHICH ENDED
AFFIRMATIVE ACTION IN THE PUBLIC
SECTOR.
>> YOU ARE ASKING THE TAXPAYERS
TO SUBSIDIZE PEOPLE LEGALLY.
I THINK THIS IS THE WRONG WAY TO
GO.
>> SOME PEOPLE FEEL IF ANYBODY
DIDN'T GO THROUGH THE PROPER
PROCESS THAT THEY DON'T BE LONG
HERE AND I CAN'T DO ANYTHING
ABOUT THAT.
>> THESE ARE EXTRAORDINARILY
TALENTED PEOPLE.
IN THE CURRENT YEAR WITH ALL OF
THE CHALLENGERS WE HAVE IN
CALIFORNIA WE CANNOT AFFORD TO
WASTE THE TALENTS.
IT WILL KOR ONLY A PORTION OF
THE FEES PLUS 5,000 DOLLARS.
>>> ABC 7 NEWS.
>> OO THE FACT OF GIVING BACK
AND SHARING THE WEALTH IS VERY
MUCH ALIVE FOR HOLIDAYS.
IN SAN FRANCISCO THE CHURCH WAS
PACKED WITH PEOPLE YESTERDAY.
EACH ONE RECEIVED A BLANKET
DONATED THE UNIVERSITY.
THEY HAVE COLLECTED BLANKETS AND
PASSED THEM OUT TO THOSE IN
NEED.
SOGGY WEATHER>> THEY WOULD LIKE
TO SEE MORE TEMPERATE WEATHER
FOR THOSE GETTING OUT TO SHOP.
>> LAST WEEKEND IS ALWAYS GOOD.
>> BEFORE THIS ONE COMING UP.
>> THAT IS PRETTY FAR OUT AS WE
HEAD OUT RIGHT NOW FROM OUR
CAMERA.
TEMPERATURES ARE MILD.
WE ARE NOT AS COLD AS YESTERDAY.
MOST PEOPLE WILL SEE SHOWERS
FROM TIME TO TIME TODAY AND THE
REST OF YOU LIVE DOPPLER 7 HD
RIGHT NOW A FEW AREAS OF LIGHT
SHOWERS IN THE NORTH BAY AROUND
SANTA ROSA.
YOU CAN SEE A FEW LIGHT AREAS IN
THE NORTH BAY.
TEMPERATURES 3 MILES FROM 43 IN
FAIRFIELD 46 IN FREMONT.
YESTERDAY THE WECH MUCH MUCH
WARMER.
GOOD MORNING NAPA WITH 45 NOT
TOO MUCH FOG RIGHT TO YNOW TO W
ABOUT.
NAPA TO FAIRFIELD IN SANTA ROSA.
13 DEGREES MILDER THAN YESTERDAY
MORNING.
8 DEGREES WARMER THAN HALF-MOON
BAY.
LIGHT SHOWERS AROUND THIS
MORNING.
MORE SHOWERS WE CAN SEE THEM
ANYWHERE BUT FAVORING THE
COASTAL HILLS.
HEAVIER RAIN WHEN THE NEXT
SYSTEM WILL BRING ANYWHERE FROM
HALF INCH TO AN INCH IN THE
NORTH BAY.
WE ARE UNDER THE WARM SECTOR
RIGHT NOW.
LIGHT RAIN FROM TIME TO TIME.
HEAVIER RAIN HOLDS ON OFF.
HERE IS A LOOK AT THE TIME LINE.
BETWEEN 8 AND 9:00 YOU CAN SEE
THE LIGHT SHOWER ACTIVITY.
BY 9, 10:00 TONIGHT NAPA SAN
FRANCISCO LOOKING AT THE WET
WEATHER.
MONDAY MORNING COMMUTE THROUGH
EARLY MORNING HOURS.
WE HAVE THE RAIN BY THE NOON
PARTIAL AFTERNOON CLEARING.
THIS TAKES US INTO TUESDAY AS
WELL AS WEDNESDAY.
53 IN OAKLAND 54 SAN JOSE.
WE ARE LOOKING AT MILDER SUNNIER
CONDITIONS WITH MID 50s AND A
LOOK AHEAD THAT BREAK TUESDAY,
WEDNESDAY.
IT LOOKS LIKE STRONGER SYSTEMS
THURSDAY FRIDAY BEGINS WINTER
INTO NEXT WEEKEND.
>> THANK YOU, LISA.
THERE IS A WOMAN WHO IS PUTTING
UP QUITE A FIGHT TO GET HER PET
BACK.
THIS WANDERING MONKEY MADE
INTERNATIONAL VIEWS.
NOW THE SAGA TO GET HIM BACK IS
TAKING A NEW TWIST.
WE HAVE THAT STRAIGHT AHEAD.
>> THE OWNER OF A WANDERING
MONKEY IS TRYING TO GET HIM
BACK.
HE WAS FOUND WANDERING IN A
TORONTO IKEA PARKING LOT LAST
WEEKEND.
CHECK THEM HIM OUT HE HAS ON THE
BIG WARM COAT.
THE MONKEY WAS ILLEGALLY TAKEN
FROM HER AND MOVED TO A PRIME
MATE SANK SAR RE.
THE WOMAN SAYS DARWIN CONSIDERS
HER HIS MOTHER.
>>> COMING UP NEXT AT 6:00 THE
LATEST IN THE INVESTIGATION AND
THE AFTERMATH OF THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL TRAGEDY.
A LIVE INTERVIEW IN THE NEWS.
POLICE ARE CLOSING IN ON A
GUNMAN WANTED FOR A SHOOTING IN
A TRANSIT CENTER IN SAN RAF
FELL.
Before cold & flu season,
help prevent
with Lysol Disinfectant Spray.
And use the Lysol
No Touch Hand Soap
for 10 times more protection
with each wash.
This season, a good
offense is the best defense.
Lysol.
Mission For Health.
>> IN THE NEWS THIS MONDAY
MORNING DISZ 16TH THEY AWAIT THE
ARRIVAL OF THE PRESIDENT TO
SHARE IN THE BRIGRIEF OF FRIDAY
SCHOOL TRAGEDY.
PRAYERS FOR THE VICTIMS AND
THEIR FAMILIES.
MANY ARE TRYING TO MAKE SENSE OF
THE SENSELESS BY RELYING ON
THEIR FAITH.
A THREAT CAUSES A BIG SCARE ON
THE STREETS IN THE HEART OF SAN
FRANCISCO.
I AM CAROLYN TYLER.
A QUIET NEW ENGLAND TOWN IS
GRIEVING THIS WEEKEND AS THEY
CONTINUE TO SEARCH FOR ANSWERS.
PARENTS ARE TALKING ABOUT THEIR
PREM DOUSE LOSS.
TEACHERS ARE HONORED FOR THEIR
HEROIC SHIELDING CHILDREN AND
SAVING LIVES.
THE STATE MEDICAL EXAMINER SAYS
BELIEVES ALL OF THE CHILDREN
KILLED WERE 1ST GRADERS BETWEEN
6 AND 7 YEARS OLD.
AS THEY SEARCH FOR EVIDENCE OF
ANY CRACK AND CREVICE THE
COMMUNITY IS TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT HOW TO COPE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL MEET WITH
THE FAMILIES WHO LOST LOVED