WE NEVER GIVE UP FIGHTING
FOR CHILDREN
LIKE LITTLE ALEJANDRO.
A FEW DAYS BEFORE CHRISTMAS,
2-YEAR-OLD ALEJANDRO
WAS HAVING HEADACHES SO SEVERE
THAT HIS PEDIATRICIAN
ORDERED A CAT SCAN.
SO THE NEXT DAY,
THE PEDIATRICIAN CALLED ME.
HE SAID, UH, "YOU NEED TO
COME OVER WITH YOUR WIFE,
BECAUSE I NEED TO TALK TO YOU."
SO I CALLED MY WIFE AND I SAID,
"THERE'S SOMETHING VERY WRONG
WITH ALEJANDRO."
HE KNEW. HE KNEW.
HE TOLD ME. MY HUSBAND.
HE KNEW THERE WAS
SOMETHING BAD.
HE SAID, "THE PEDIATRICIAN WANTS
TO SPEAK WITH US IN PERSON NOW."
I DROVE 120 MILES AN HOUR.
I GOT TO THE DOCTOR'S OFFICE,
AND HE GOES,
"LOOK, UH,
ALEJANDRO HAS A BRAIN TUMOR."
"WHAT DO YOU MEAN
A BRAIN TUMOR?"
HE GOES, "YEAH,
HE HAS A BRAIN TUMOR,
AND HE NEEDS TO GO
INTO SURGERY TOMORROW."
THE WORLD STOPPED.
THIS CANNOT BE HAPPENING,
AT LEAST NOT TO US.
THIS ALWAYS HAPPENS
TO SOMEONE ELSE.
[ Marlo ] ALEJANDRO WAS
DIAGNOSED WITH MEDULLOBLASTOMA,
A DEADLY BRAIN TUMOR,
AND HE HAD EMERGENCY SURGERY
TO REMOVE THE TUMOR.
THEN HIS PEDIATRICIAN
REFERRED ALEJANDRO
TO ST. JUDE CHILDREN'S
RESEARCH HOSPITAL
IN AN ALL-OUT EFFORT
TO SAVE HIS LIFE.
[ David ]
THESE PEOPLE MEAN BUSINESS.
THESE PEOPLE KNOW
WHAT THEY'RE DOING.
[ Woman ]
GOOD JOB, ALEJANDRO.
LET ME SHOW TO YOU.
[ David ] I HAD THE FIRST
MEETING WITH THE ONCOLOGISTS,
AND THEY SAID, "LOOK.
YOU KNOW, THIS IS WHAT IT IS.
"THIS IS WHAT HE HAS.
THIS IS WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO.
AND THIS IS WHY
IT NEEDS TO BE DONE."
THEY'RE THE ANSWER
TO THE PRAYERS.
TICKLE, TICKLE,
TICKLE!
HE'S A VERY CHEERFUL BOY.
HE'S SMILING. HE'S PLAYING.
HE LIKES TO SING.
♪ OLD MacDONALD HAD A FARM
♪ E-I-E-I-O
I SEE ALEJANDRO, WHO'S A LITTLE
2 1/2-YEAR-OLD KID WHO...
WHO HAS A CENTRAL LINE,
WHO GETS PUT IN CHEMO.
THEY TAKE BLOOD SAMPLES
EVERY OTHER DAY, AND MRI'S.
AND THEY PUT HIM TO SLEEP.
AND THEY DO ALL THE STUFF.
AND POOR GUY JUST WAKES UP
THE NEXT DAY WITH A SMILE.
[ babbling ]
WHERE'D YOU GO?
[ David speaking Spanish ]
[ chuckles ]
[ Marlo ] TODAY
ALEJANDRO AND HIS PARENTS
ARE CELEBRATING TWO BIG EVENTS,
HIS THIRD BIRTHDAY
AND THE END OF CHEMOTHERAPY
AND RADIATION.
[ howls ]
[ Marlo ] THEY'RE JUST WAITING
FOR THE RESULT OF THE FINAL MRI
AND THEN THEY'LL BE HEADED HOME
FOR THREE MONTHS.
BUT A PHONE CALL
FROM ALEJANDRO'S DOCTOR
SUDDENLY CHANGES EVERYTHING.
THERE'S A RELAPSE.
UH, FOUND A TUMOR
ON HIS SPINE...SPINAL CORD
THE DAY WE HAD OUR BAGS PACKED,
THE DAY OF HIS BIRTHDAY, ALSO.
[ Inez ] WE HAD GIFTS
AND PICTURES FOR ALL THE NURSES.
SO IT WAS HARD.
♪
[ David ]
WE'RE STARTING ALL OVER AGAIN.
WE JUST HAVE TO REGROUP
AND REALIGN OURSELVES.
QUITTING IS NOT AN OPTION.
PRAY FOR THE BEST.
[ monitor beeping ]
HERE GOES ONE MORE TEST.
BUT IT NEEDS TO BE DONE.
[ sighs ]
[ speaking Spanish ]
YOU KNOW,
WE'RE TAKING ONE DAY AT A TIME.
IT'S IN THE HANDS OF THESE
SCIENTISTS, THESE DOCTORS.
IT'S JUST A HUGE ARMY OF...
OF PEOPLE BUILT OF HOPE
AND LOVE AND CARING.
ST. JUDE BASICALLY MEANS HOPE.
YOU HOPE FOR THE RESEARCH.
YOU HOPE FOR THE CONTRIBUTIONS.
YOU HOPE FOR...
FOR THESE DOCTORS.
THE DEFINITION OF HOPE
IS ST. JUDE.
THAT'S ALEJANDRO'S STORY.
♪
[ Marlo ]
ALEJANDRO'S FIGHTING SPIRIT
IS SHARED BY EVERYONE
AT ST. JUDE.
THE DOCTORS. THE NURSES.
THE RESEARCHERS.
AND PEOPLE LIKE YOU,
OUR PARTNERS IN HOPE.
WE NEVER GIVE UP.
AND IT'S HOW ALEJANDRO
AND HIS PARENTS
KEEP FIGHTING AGAINST ALL ODDS.
BUT THEY CAN'T DO IT ALONE.
PLEASE, HELP SAVE A CHILD
LIKE ALEJANDRO.
BECOME A PARTNER IN HOPE TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
CALL RIGHT NOW
AND BECOME A ST. JUDE
PARTNER IN HOPE.
YOUR COMMITMENT OF $19 A MONTH
WILL HELP
SAVE CHILDREN'S LIVES.
WE TREAT CHILDREN FROM ALL
50 STATES AND AROUND THE WORLD.
AND FOR MANY OF THEM,
ST. JUDE CHILDREN'S RESEARCH
HOSPITAL IS THEIR ONLY HOPE.
WHEN A FAMILY
COMES THROUGH THE DOORS HERE,
THE FIRST THING WE WANT TO DO
IS GIVE THEM HOPE.
AND THE FIRST THING WE SAY IS,
"WE'RE GONNA DO EVERYTHING
WE CAN TO SAVE YOUR CHILD."
[ Male Announcer ] ST. JUDE
DEPENDS ON YOUR SUPPORT
FOR THE RESEARCH AND TREATMENTS
THESE CHILDREN NEED TODAY.
NO CHILD IS EVER TURNED AWAY
BECAUSE OF THE FAMILY'S
INABILITY TO PAY.
THAT'S WHY YOUR CALL --
RIGHT NOW -- IS SO IMPORTANT.
I SEE THE CHILDREN
THAT THEY'RE HELPING TODAY,
AND THAT COULD BE
MY GRANDCHILD TOMORROW.
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR RESEARCH BREAKTHROUGHS
HAVE HELPED MORE THAN TRIPLE
THE SURVIVAL RATE
FOR CHILDHOOD CANCERS.
ST. JUDE EVEN COVERS
THE COST OF TRAVEL,
FOOD AND HOUSING
FOR A PARENT AND CHILD.
IT'S THE VERY FIRST
PEDIATRIC INSTITUTION
EVER TO PUT RESEARCH
AND TREATMENT UNDER ONE ROOF.
AND EVERY DISCOVERY MADE
AT ST. JUDE
IS SHARED FREELY WITH DOCTORS
AND SCIENTISTS WORLDWIDE.
CALL NOW AND BECOME
A ST. JUDE PARTNER IN HOPE.
JUST $19 A MONTH
WILL HELP FIND THE CURES
TO SAVE CHILDREN'S LIVES.
GOD BLESS OUR PARTNERS IN HOPE.
WE'D BE LOST WITHOUT THEM.
I HAVE TO DO SOMETHING.
WE ALL HAVE TO DO SOMETHING.
THESE ARE OUR CHILDREN.
[ Male Announcer ] CALL NOW
AND JOIN THOUSANDS OF AMERICANS
WHO ARE ST. JUDE PARTNERS
IN HOPE
WITH YOUR COMMITMENT
OF JUST $19 A MONTH.
IF YOU PREFER -- A GENEROUS
GIFT OF ANY SIZE RIGHT NOW
WILL HELP SAVE
CHILDREN'S LIVES.
YOU CAN EVEN MAKE YOUR PAYMENTS
AUTOMATICALLY
USING YOUR DEBIT
OR CREDIT CARD.
IT'S CONVENIENT,
AND IT SAVES MONEY SO MORE
GOES DIRECTLY TO THE KIDS.
IN THESE TIMES
WHEN IT'S TOUGH,
I THINK IT'S
EVEN MORE IMPORTANT TO GIVE.
[ Male Announcer ] PLEASE --
THE CHILDREN
ARE COUNTING ON YOU.
CALL NOW AND BECOME A
ST. JUDE PARTNER IN HOPE TODAY.
♪
HI, I'M TONY THOMAS.
MY FATHER,
ENTERTAINER DANNY THOMAS,
FOUNDED ST. JUDE
CHILDREN'S RESEARCH HOSPITAL
NEARLY 50 YEARS AGO.
AND I'M FOLLOWING
IN MY DAD'S FOOTSTEPS
WORKING WITH FAMILY AND FRIENDS
TO HELP FULFILL HIS DREAM,
THAT NO CHILD SHOULD DIE
IN THE DAWN OF LIFE.
I ALSO FOLLOWED MY DAD'S
FOOTSTEPS INTO SHOW BUSINESS,
PRODUCING MOVIES
AND TELEVISION SERIES.
ONE OF THE TV SHOWS I PRODUCED
WAS "THE GOLDEN GIRLS,"
AND I HAD THE PRIVILEGE
OF WORKING WITH BETTY WHITE.
BETTY IS STILL
A DEAR FRIEND TODAY,
AND SHE WAS EAGER TO HELP
THE KIDS OF ST. JUDE
AND SHARE WITH YOU
AN IMPORTANT STORY
OF ONE CHILD'S AMAZING COURAGE
AND THE BATTLE THAT GOES ON
EVERY DAY AT ST. JUDE.
NEUROBLASTOMA.
WILMS'S TUMOR. OSTEOSARCOMA.
THESE AGGRESSIVE CANCERS
ARE NO LAUGHING MATTER.
AND THE KIDS AT ST. JUDE
FIGHT THESE CANCERS EVERY DAY.
THAT'S WHY ST. JUDE RESEARCHERS
ARE ALWAYS WORKING
TO FIND NEW TREATMENTS
TO HELP THESE KIDS
SURVIVE AND THRIVE.
THE CHILD YOU'RE ABOUT TO MEET
WARMS MY HEART.
HE'S A REAL FIGHTER.
GOOD.
TAKE A BIG BREATH FOR ME.
BRANDON HAS OSTEOSARCOMA,
THE MOST COMMON FORM
OF BONE CANCER IN CHILDREN.
LET ME SEE YOUR MOUTH.
OPEN YOUR MOUTH.
THE CANCER
WAS FOUND IN HIS KNEE.
WHEN BRANDON
ARRIVED AT ST. JUDE,
DOCTORS HAD TO MOVE QUICKLY
IN ORDER TO SAVE HIS LIFE.
FEELING OKAY?
HOW'S THE OTHER LEG?
FINE.
SHOW ME THE LEG.
THEY HAD NO CHOICE
BUT TO AMPUTATE HIS LEG.
BRANDON'S GRANDMOTHER REMEMBERS
THE DAY HE WAS DIAGNOSED
IN THEIR HOMETOWN
AND THE LONG DRIVE TO ST. JUDE.
[ Lucy ]
WHEN THEY DIAGNOSED HIM,
I DIDN'T WANT TO BELIEVE IT.
I SAID, "BRANDON, CANCER? NO."
[ Lucy ]
THEY DIDN'T TELL YOU WHAT ROOM.
ROOM TWO.
I SAID, "THIS CAN'T BE."
BUT I JUST KEPT PRAYING.
LIKE THIS.
OHH.
I PRAYED ALL NIGHT. WE GOT UP
AT 6:00 IN THE MORNING.
I PRAYED, AND I PRAYED
ALL DOWN THE HIGHWAY.
WHEN I WALKED INTO ST. JUDE
AND WHEN I STEPPED
IN THAT FRONT DOOR,
IT WAS JUST LIKE
A BURDEN FELL OFF ME.
IT WAS JUST
LIKE A SPIRITUAL THING.
I WANTED TO JUST SHOUT,
"GLORY HALLELUJAH."
[ Betty ] IMMEDIATELY AFTER
BRANDON ARRIVED AT ST. JUDE,
DOCTORS DISCOVERED THAT HIS
CANCER HAD SPREAD TO HIS LUNG.
BEFORE HIS AMPUTATION,
HE HAD TO UNDERGO
A LUNG OPERATION
TO REMOVE ANY SIGNS OF TUMOR.
BUT FOR THIS BRAVE 7-YEAR-OLD,
THE BATTLE IS JUST BEGINNING.
HE NOW FACES 20 WEEKS
OF INTENSIVE CHEMOTHERAPY.
I'M PROUD TO BE HIS FATHER,
VERY PROUD.
HE'S THE STRONGEST PERSON
I EVER MET IN MY LIFE.
HE'S LIKE A HERO TO ME.
FULL OF LIFE.
HE'S JUST A VERY HAPPY KID.
LOVES EVERYONE,
AND EVERYONE LOVES HIM.
[ Lucy ] HE'S OKAY
WHILE THE CAST IS ON.
BUT WHEN YOU TAKE THE CAST OFF,
HE DON'T LIKE TO LOOK
AT HIS HIP.
[ crying ] I'M SCARED.
[ Lucy ] HE DON'T
WANT TO LOOK AT IT.
THAT'S WHAT HE KEPT SAYING,
"I'M SCARED, I'M SCARED."
HE'S SCARED OF IT.
BRANDON HAD TOLD US
THAT HE WAS AFRAID
IF HE LOOKED DOWN
THAT HE WOULD SEE HIS LEG.
IT'S ACTUALLY CALLED
PHANTOM LIMB SENSATION,
BECAUSE SOMETIMES
THEY CAN FEEL PAIN
OR THEY JUST FEEL
LIKE THEIR LEG IS THERE.
HE WAS ABSOLUTELY TERRIFIED.
[ Lucy ] JUST AMAZING,
WHAT THEY HAVE TO GO THROUGH.
♪
ALL RIGHT, SO,
YOU RELAX FOR A MINUTE.
[ Betty ] A WEEK LATER,
IT'S TIME FOR BRANDON
TO BE MEASURED
FOR HIS PERMANENT PROSTHESIS.
ONCE AGAIN,
HE MUST CONFRONT HIS FEARS.
RIGHT.
I'M USED TO LOOKING
AT IT NOW.
YOU ARE?
OH.
[ both laugh ]
[ Victoria ]
TODAY WAS AN AWESOME
BREAKTHROUGH FOR BRANDON,
THAT HE LOOKED AT HIS LEG AND
HE ACCEPTED THAT IT WAS HIS LEG.
THERE IT IS. YOUR LEG.
HE WOULD TOUCH IT, WHICH HELPS
WITH DESENSITIZING HIS LEG.
OKAY, NOW ROLL OVER
ON YOUR SIDE. FACE DADDY.
SO TODAY WAS JUST A PHENOMENAL
BREAKTHROUGH FOR HIM.
♪
[ Betty ]
IT'S BARELY BEEN A MONTH
SINCE SURGERY
TOOK BRANDON'S LEG.
BUT TODAY HE IS DETERMINED
TO TAKE HIS FIRST STEPS.
YOU JUST HAVE TO
PRACTICE ON IT.
BREAKFAST?
I'D REALLY LIKE YOU
TO BE ABLE TO
WALK WITHOUT YOUR CRUTCHES,
OKAY?
ME, TOO.
YOU WOULD?
[ indistinct conversation ]
[ Jimmy ] WHEN I SAW HIM WALK
FOR THE FIRST TIME,
I WAS JUST AMAZED.
IT WAS JUST LIKE
A GIFT FROM GOD --
LIKE SEEING YOUR BABY WALK
FOR THE FIRST TIME.
VERY NICE!
[ Betty ] THOSE CLOSE TO BRANDON
AGREE THAT HIS DREAM TO RUN
AND PLAY SPORTS AGAIN
WILL COME TRUE.
BUT BECAUSE THE CANCER
SPREAD TO HIS LUNG,
THE PATH TO LONG-TERM SURVIVAL
IS MORE DIFFICULT
AND MORE DANGEROUS.
[ Lucy ] YOU COULDN'T BE AT
NO BETTER PLACE THAN ST. JUDE.
THERE'S JUST SO MUCH LOVE HERE.
IT'S REAL.
THAT'S WHY I THANK GOD FOR
ST. JUDE EVERY DAY OF MY LIFE.
♪
THIS IS A WONDERFUL PLACE.
IT BREAKS MY HEART TO TELL YOU
BRANDON LOST HIS BATTLE
WITH CANCER.
BUT BECAUSE OF THE TREATMENT
HE RECEIVED AT ST. JUDE,
BEFORE HE DIED,
HE WAS ABLE TO RETURN TO BEING
THE GREAT KID HE ALWAYS WAS,
FULL OF LIFE AND ENERGY.
HE BECAME AN HONOR STUDENT.
AND HE WAS ABLE TO ENJOY
TWO MORE PRECIOUS YEARS
RIDING HIS BIKE,
PLAYING HIS VIDEO GAMES,
AND LOVING HIS FAMILY.
IN MEMORY OF BRANDON,
AND FOR EVERY CHILD
STILL FIGHTING TO LIVE --
BECOME A ST. JUDE
PARTNER IN HOPE TODAY.
♪
IMAGINE YOUR DOCTOR TELLS YOU
THAT YOUR CHILD
ONLY HAS MONTHS TO LIVE.
THAT THE SMALL RED DOTS
ON HIS ARM AREN'T CHICKEN POX,
BUT A RARE
TERMINAL BONE DISEASE.
AS A FATHER
AND A GRANDFATHER MYSELF,
I CAN'T IMAGINE HEARING
SUCH A TERRIBLE PROGNOSIS.
BUT FOR LIAM AND HIS PARENTS,
GIVING UP ISN'T AN OPTION.
1, 2, 3!
[ laughs ]
1 -- NO!
I SHOULDN'T COUNT
FOR YOU!
[ Regina ] LIAM WAS DIAGNOSED
WITH MYELODYSPLASTIC SYNDROME,
WHICH IS CALLED MDS.
BASICALLY ALL OF HIS CELLS --
RED, WHITE AND PLATELETS --
WEREN'T FORMING CORRECTLY
AND ARE MISSING
THEIR SEVENTH CHROMOSOME.
I THINK TWO IN A MILLION
CHILDREN GET IT.
I HAD ASKED, "IS IT SURVIVABLE?"
AND THEY SAID,
"NO. NOT REALLY."
IT WAS OVER THE PHONE
THAT WE WERE TOLD THAT.
AND I THOUGHT MAYBE I HEARD IT
WRONG OR MAYBE I ASKED WRONG.
I SAID, "NOT REALLY SURVIVABLE?"
AND THEY SAID, "NO."
IT WAS BASICALLY,
"HE'S GONNA DIE SOON."
[ Tom ] REGINA AND HER HUSBAND
DESPERATELY SEARCHED
THE INTERNET FOR HELP
AND ANY SIGN OF HOPE.
[ Regina ] WE CAME ACROSS A LOT
OF DIFFERENT WEBSITES
AND A LOT OF DIFFERENT HOSPITALS
AND ORGANIZATIONS,
BUT THE ONLY ONE THAT SHOWED
ANY SURVIVAL RATES AT ALL
WAS ST. JUDE.
WE CAN MAKE
A MAGIC TRICK.
[ Tom ] WITHIN A WEEK,
LIAM WAS REFERRED
TO ST. JUDE CHILDREN'S
RESEARCH HOSPITAL,
WHERE HE RECEIVED
A BONE-MARROW TRANSPLANT.
[ indistinct conversation ]
DOCTORS AT ST. JUDE
HAVE PIONEERED THE USE
OF THESE TRANSPLANTS
FOR THE TREATMENT OF MDS.
[ Regina ] THEY WERE EXPERIENCED
WITH THIS KIND OF DISORDER,
AND AS RARE AS IT IS,
THAT'S A BIG DEAL.
THEY HAD SOME THINGS IN MIND
THAT WOULD SPECIFICALLY HELP HIM
AND INCREASE HIS CHANCES.
LIAM IS ENERGETIC.
HE'S FEARLESS.
HE ALWAYS IS LAUGHING.
HE DOESN'T SEEM TO NOTICE
THAT HE HAS CANCER.
ON YOUR MARKS,
GET SET, GO!
[ laughing ]
HE LIKES TO MAKE UP STORIES.
HE LIKES TO MAKE UP SONGS,
AND HE WILL BECOME ANY CHARACTER
THAT HE WANTS TO.
DR. LIAM.
THINGS CAN GO BAD VERY QUICKLY,
WE'VE LEARNED.
A COUPLE WEEKS AGO,
WE STARTED HAVING SEIZURES.
HIS BRAIN HAD STARTED SWELLING.
THEY HAD PEOPLE COME IN AND
IMMEDIATELY TAKE CARE OF HIM.
I TRY VERY HARD TO NOT CRY
IN FRONT OF HIM,
BUT ONCE IN A WHILE,
YOU CAN'T NOT CRY,
AND HE'LL COME OVER
AND WIPE AWAY MY TEARS
AND GIVE ME A HUG AND KISS.
AND...IT MELTS YOUR HEART.
♪
[ Tom ] THIS VISIT MARKS
THE THIRD YEAR
SINCE LIAM'S
BONE-MARROW TRANSPLANT.
BUT IT'S STILL TOO EARLY
IN THE BATTLE
FOR LIAM TO CLAIM VICTORY.
[ Liam ] HER NAME IS STEPHANIE,
AND SHE'S MY GIRLFRIEND.
[ Regina ]
LIAM HAS MADE A LOT OF FRIENDS.
[ Liam ]
'CAUSE SHE'S MY GIRLFRIEND,
AND SHE'S GONNA
MARRY ME.
AND STEPHANIE
HAD HER TRANSPLANT,
UM, FOR AML, WHICH IS SIMILAR.
IT'S A FORM OF LEUKEMIA.
"I LOVE LIAM."
I CAN'T SEE
YOUR NAME ON IT.
AND HE JUST LOVES TO KNOW
THAT HE GETS TO SEE HER.
[ giggling ]
IT STILL BREAKS MY HEART
'CAUSE WHENEVER I START TO TALK
TO HIM ABOUT HER AT HOME,
HIS RESPONSE A LOT OF THE TIMES
IS, "DID SHE DIE?"
♪
TOUCH MY FINGER.
TOUCH YOUR NOSE.
BEFORE WE CAME HERE,
WE WERE TOLD LIAM WOULD DIE.
I PUT "M-O-M" ON IT
FOR MOM.
ST. JUDE SAID IT WAS SURVIVABLE.
AND THEY WERE WILLING
TO TRY AND TREAT HIM
WHEN OTHER PLACES WEREN'T.
SO WE'RE JUST ETERNALLY GRATEFUL
FOR THIS PLACE.
♪
[ Tom ] ONLY TWO
IN A MILLION CHILDREN
GET MYELODYSPLASTIC SYNDROME.
MOST DO NOT SURVIVE.
BUT THANKS TO ST. JUDE,
LIAM'S FAMILY HAS HAD
3 MORE PRECIOUS YEARS WITH HIM.
BUT THE RELAPSE RATE FOR MDS
IS 75%,
AND IT COULD RETURN AT ANY TIME.
THAT'S WHY WE WILL
KEEP FIGHTING FOR LIAM.
I INVITE YOU TO JOIN US
TO HELP CHILDREN LIKE LIAM.
PLEASE BECOME A ST. JUDE
PARTNER IN HOPE TODAY!
♪
LIFE IS A GIFT.
EVEN MORE SO
FOR A CHILD BATTLING CANCER.
THAT'S WHY THE DOCTORS
AND THE SCIENTISTS
WORKING TOGETHER AT ST. JUDE
ARE SO IMPORTANT.
ST. JUDE WAS THE FIRST
PEDIATRIC INSTITUTION
EVER TO PUT RESEARCH
AND TREATMENT UNDER ONE ROOF.
I'VE SUPPORTED ST. JUDE
FOR YEARS.
I'VE PERSONALLY SEEN
THE REAL HOPE
FAMILIES GET AT ST. JUDE,
EVEN WHEN THE ODDS ARE STACKED
SO HIGH AGAINST THEM.
YOU'RE GOING TO LOVE
THIS LITTLE GUY.
MEET HAYDEN.
MAMA, IF MY HAIR COMES BACK,
CAN I DYE IT BLUE?
LIGHT BLUE OR DARK BLUE?
LIGHT BLUE.
LIGHT BLUE?
[ Christy ] HAYDEN HAS
BEEN DIAGNOSED WITH ATRT...
♪
...ATYPICAL TERATOID
RHABDOID TUMOR.
♪
IT IS LOCATED
IN THE BACK OF THE BRAIN.
[ Woman ] HOLD YOUR BREATH.
[ Christy ] IT'S VERY SERIOUS.
THERE IS NO CURE.
THEY SNUCK IN ANOTHER
APPOINTMENT ON US.
HE'S DOING GOOD.
HE'S -- HE'S TOUGH.
I CRY A LOT HERE.
BUT IT'S NOT
A DEPRESSING PLACE AT ALL.
BECAUSE, AROUND HERE,
KIDS ARE NUMBER ONE.
[ monitor beeping ]
HE'S BEEN FEELING PRETTY LOUSY.
THE CHEMO'S REALLY HIT HIM HARD
THIS TIME.
AND HE'S BEEN IN A LOT OF PAIN.
THE PAST THREE NIGHTS, HE'S BEEN
UP ALL NIGHT, GETTING SICK.
HIS STOMACH IS JUST BASICALLY
RAW ON THE INSIDE.
THEY CALL IT
HIGH-DOSE CHEMOTHERAPY.
IT'S PROBABLY ONE OF
THE HIGHEST DOSES ANYBODY GETS.
EXTREMELY DANGEROUS.
[ Gloria ] ALTHOUGH
THERE IS NO CURE FOR ATRT,
A BONE-MARROW TRANSPLANT
CAN SAVE HAYDEN'S LIFE.
TODAY, HE IS HAVING
HIS OWN MARROW HARVESTED.
AND THEN,
AFTER THE MARROW IS TESTED
AND HAYDEN IS GIVEN
INTENSE CHEMOTHERAPY,
DOCTORS AT ST. JUDE WILL USE
THIS MARROW FOR HIS TRANSPLANT.
♪
HEY. COME ON.
HOW ARE YOU?
IT'S BEEN SIX MONTHS
SINCE HAYDEN'S HARVEST
AND TRANSPLANT.
TODAY HE IS BACK AT ST. JUDE
FOR THERAPY, A HEARING TEST,
AND A CHECK
OF HIS COGNITIVE SKILLS.
BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY,
HE'S HERE FOR AN MRI
OF HIS SPINE AND HIS BRAIN
TO SEE IF THERE ARE ANY SIGNS
OF TUMOR.
[ Christy ] HE REALLY LOOKS
THE BEST WE'VE SEEN HIM LOOK
IN A LONG TIME.
BUT IN THE SAME SENSE,
IT'S SCARY.
JUST BECAUSE
WE KNOW HE LOOKS GOOD
DOESN'T MEAN THINGS
ARE GOOD ON THE INSIDE.
[ Gloria ]
HAYDEN AND HIS PARENTS
FINALLY GET THE NEWS THEY'VE
BEEN SO ANXIOUSLY WAITING FOR.
THERE'S NO EVIDENCE OF --
OF TUMOR.
IT LOOKS GOOD.
[ laughter ]
TODAY HAYDEN IS GOING HOME
TO HIS FAMILY AND FRIENDS.
BUT IN THREE MONTHS
HE'LL BE BACK AT ST. JUDE
FOR MORE TESTS TO SEE
IF THE CANCER HAS RETURNED.
[ Christy ] WE'VE GOT TO FIND
SOME WAYO BEAT THIS CANCER.
YOU DON'T KNOW WHEN
YOU'RE GONNA BE IN MY SHOES.
IT MAY NOT BE YOUR OWN CHILD.
IT MAY BE
YOUR BEST FRIEND'S CHILD.
IT MAY BE YOUR GRANDCHILD.
BUT CHANCES ARE, AT SOME POINT,
THIS IS GONNA TOUCH
SOMEBODY IN YOUR LIFE.
NO CHILD EVER, EVER
SHOULD HAVE TO GO THROUGH THIS.
WE ARE STILL HOPING THAT --
THAT THERE'S A MIRACLE
AROUND THE CORNER.
♪
OPEN YOUR MOUTH FOR ME.
OPEN WIDE.
[ Gloria ] THREE MONTHS LATER,
HAYDEN IS BACK AT ST. JUDE.
WHAT DO YOU WANT
FOR YOUR BIRTHDAY?
A SNAKE.
HIS FACE IS SWOLLEN
BECAUSE OF THE DRUGS TO
RELEASE PRESSURE ON HIS BRAIN.
THE TUMOR IS GROWING AGAIN.
THIS TIME NOTHING HAS
BEEN ABLE TO STOP THE CANCER.
[ Christy ]
WE WENT TO SEE THE HOCKEY GAME.
WHENEVER WE CAN,
WE'LL GO DO SOMETHING FUN.
HAYDEN ALREADY KNOWS
THAT AT THIS POINT
THERE IS NO DRUG THAT'S
GONNA MAKE THE TUMOR GO AWAY.
HE KNOWS WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN.
SOMETIMES HE'LL GET SCARED
AND HE'LL CRY,
BUT HAYDEN ALSO HAS
A DEEP FAITH,
AND HE KNOWS
THAT HE'S GONNA BE IN HEAVEN
WITH HIS OTHER FRIENDS FROM HERE
THAT HAVE PASSED ON.
HE KNOWS THAT THERE WON'T BE
ANY MORE PAIN, AND...
WE'VE TOLD HIM
WHEN HIS TIME IS READY,
IT'S TIME FOR HIM TO GO,
THAT HE NEEDS TO GO.
♪
[ Gloria ] DESPITE OUR BEST
EFFORTS TO SAVE HIS LIFE,
HAYDEN LOST HIS BATTLE.
♪
[ Christy ]
TOWARDS THE END,
HE JUST HANDLED EVERYTHING
WITH SUCH GRACE AND DIGNITY,
AND HE WAS JUST SO BRAVE.
HE WANTED TO HELP OTHER KIDS.
HE KNEW HOW HARD IT WAS
TO HAVE CANCER,
AND HE WOULD NEVER WANT
ANYBODY ELSE
TO HAVE TO GO THROUGH
WHAT HE WENT THROUGH.
WE WOULD DO ANYTHING
FOR OUR HOSPITAL.
THERE IS HOPE.
NOT EVERY CHILD HAS TO LOSE
THEIR LIFE TO CANCER.
♪
THERE'S NO CURE YET
FOR THE KIND OF BRAIN TUMOR
THAT CLAIMED
HAYDEN'S YOUNG LIFE.
BUT ST. JUDE IS LEADING THE WAY
TO FINDING ONE.
AND IT WILL HAPPEN ONE DAY
BECAUSE OF PEOPLE LIKE YOU
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY
WHO REALLY CARE
ABOUT THESE CHILDREN,
OUR PARTNERS IN HOPE,
WHO ARE ALL IN THIS FIGHT
TOGETHER.
SO JOIN US TODAY.
THESE CHILDREN NEED
EVERY MEMBER OF OUR TEAM
TO HELP THEM WIN
THEIR BATTLE AGAINST CANCER.
MANY HAVE COME TO ST. JUDE
BECAUSE THEY HAVE
NOWHERE ELSE TO TURN.
CHILDREN LIKE GRACIE,
WHO WAS JUST A YEAR OLD
WHEN DOCTORS IN HER HOMETOWN
DISCOVERED A TUMOR IN HER BRAIN.
THEY TOLD US
THAT IT HAD SPREAD TO HER SPINE
AND THEY SAID THERE'S
REALLY NOTHING WE CAN DO.
THEY SAID THE DISEASE
WAS TERMINAL.
CAN YOU SAY, "AIRPLANE"?
AIRPLANE.
VERY GOOD.
MAMA.
[ Marlo ] ON A FRIEND'S ADVICE,
GRACIE'S PARENTS
SENT HER MEDICAL RECORDS
AND SCANS TO ST. JUDE.
AND WITHIN A FEW HOURS,
GRACIE'S DAD GOT A CALL
FROM ST. JUDE ON HIS CELLPHONE.
OUR TEAM OF DOCTORS AND
SCIENTISTS HAD ENCOURAGING NEWS.
WE FOUND THAT THE CANCER
HAD NOT SPREAD TO HER SPINE.
WE WERE PICKING OUT SONGS
FOR HER FUNERAL,
I WAS CRYING
AND I WAS GIVING HER A THUMBS UP
AND I WAS SAYING, "IT'S MEMPHIS,
AND THEY DON'T SEE
THE TUMOR ON HER SPINE,"
AND THAT GAVE US
THE FIRST GLIMMER OF HOPE.
[ Marlo ] GRACIE SPENT
THE NEXT 12 MONTHS AT ST. JUDE,
UNDERGOING MORE THAN 30 ROUNDS
OF THREE-DIMENSIONAL
CONFORMAL RADIATION,
A CUTTING-EDGE PROCEDURE
THAT ATTACKS THE TUMOR
WHILE PROTECTING HEALTHY AREAS
OF A YOUNG, DEVELOPING BRAIN
LIKE GRACIE'S.
[ Julie ]
SHE HAS A BRAIN TUMOR.
WELL, THE BRAIN-TUMOR EXPERTS
ARE AT ST. JUDE,
AND THEY DEAL WITH THIS
EVERY SINGLE DAY.
THEY SEE HUNDREDS OF CASES.
[ Dr. Merchant ] IT'S HARD
TO EXPLAIN TO A 2-YEAR-OLD
THAT BAD-TASTING MEDICINE
WILL MAKE YOU FEEL BETTER
OR A NEEDLE'S GOING TO MAKE YOU
FEEL BETTER IN A LITTLE BIT,
BUT SHE'S BEEN A TROOPER
THROUGH IT ALL.
THERE WE GO.
[ Julie ] THAT'S THE FIRST THING
WE SAID IS,
"THANK YOU
FOR THAT HOPE YOU GAVE US,"
'CAUSE WE DID NOT HAVE ANY
UNTIL WE CAME HERE.
[ Marlo ]
TWO YEARS AFTER DIAGNOSIS,
GRACIE IS CELEBRATING
HER THIRD BIRTHDAY, CANCER FREE.
LOOK HOW BIG
SHE'S GETTING!
IT'S HARD TO BELIEVE THAT GRACIE
IS THE SAME LITTLE GIRL
WHOSE PARENT'S HAD PICKED OUT
SONGS FOR HER FUNERAL,
ALL THOSE MONTHS AGO.
[ Julie ] LOOK AT HER.
HER HEAD IS HELD UP STRAIGHT.
SHE JUST HAS A GLOW ABOUT HER.
WHAT DO YOU ALWAYS WEAR?
UM, PINK DRESS.
[ Nathan ] THESE ARE DAYS
SHE WASN'T SUPPOSED TO HAVE.
TWO YEARS DOWN THE ROAD,
WE'RE WELL PAST
HER THIRD BIRTHDAY,
I THINK OF THAT EVERY NIGHT
WHEN I TUCK HER IN.
I CAN'T TELL YOU HOW PROUD I AM
AS A MOM.
I CAN'T IMAGINE
GOING THROUGH WHAT
I'VE WATCHED HER GO THROUGH.
♪
SHE'S DONE IT AS A BABY,
AS A 2-YEAR-OLD.
HAD IT NOT BEEN FOR ST. JUDE,
WE WOULD NOT HAVE HER TODAY.
THIS HOSPITAL
HAS FOUGHT FOR GRACE.
GRACE HAS FOUGHT DILIGENTLY,
AND SHE'S JUST REMAINED
SO STRONG,
AND I JUST LOOK AT HER
AND MARVEL AT THAT.
RUN THROUGH THESE HALLS
TWO YEARS LATER?
IT'S MIRACULOUS.
[ Male Announcer ] YOU CAN
HELP SAVE A CHILD'S LIFE.
CALL RIGHT NOW AND BECOME
A ST. JUDE PARTNER IN HOPE.
JUST $19 A MONTH
WILL HELP PROVIDE
BREAKTHROUGH RESEARCH,
TREATMENTS AND CURES.
WE HELP CHILDREN FROM ALL
50 STATES AND AROUND THE WORLD.
AND FOR MANY OF THEM,
ST. JUDE CHILDREN'S RESEARCH
HOSPITAL IS THEIR ONLY HOPE.
IT TAKES ALL OF US
TO MAKE THIS HAPPEN --
THE DOCTORS, THE SCIENTISTS,
AND THE PARTNERS IN HOPE.
[ Male Announcer ] ST. JUDE
CHILDREN'S RESEARCH HOSPITAL
BEGAN AS THE DREAM OF ONE MAN,
DANNY THOMAS.
MY FATHER'S DREAM
SIMPLY WAS THAT
NO CHILD SHOULD DIE
IN THE DAWN OF LIFE
AND THAT'S WHAT
WE'RE ALL STILL WORKING TOWARD.
ST. JUDE IS DOING GREAT THINGS.
AND THEY ARE ON THE CUTTING EDGE
OF THE NEW TECHNOLOGY.
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR RESEARCH BREAKTHROUGHS
HAVE HELPED MORE THAN TRIPLE
THE SURVIVAL RATE
FOR CHILDHOOD CANCERS.
WHEN ST. JUDE OPENED
ONLY 4 OUT OF 100 CHILDREN
SURVIVED THE MOST COMMON
CHILDHOOD CANCER.
TODAY, 94% OF KIDS
WITH THAT DISEASE
GET TO GO HOME
AND KEEP GROWING.
NO CHILD IS EVER TURNED AWAY
FOR A FAMILY'S
INABILITY TO PAY.
CALL NOW AND BECOME
A ST. JUDE PARTNER IN HOPE.
JUST $19 A MONTH
WILL HELP FIND THE CURES
TO SAVE CHILDREN'S LIVES.
CALL NOW AND JOIN
THOUSANDS OF AMERICANS
WHO ARE ST. JUDE PARTNERS
IN HOPE
WITH YOUR COMMITMENT
OF JUST $19 A MONTH.
IF YOU PREFER -- A GENEROUS
GIFT OF ANY SIZE RIGHT NOW
WILL HELP SAVE
CHILDREN'S LIVES.
YOU CAN EVEN MAKE YOUR PAYMENTS
AUTOMATICALLY
USING YOUR DEBIT
OR CREDIT CARD.
IT SAVES MONEY
SO MORE OF YOUR DONATION
GOES DIRECTLY TO HELP CHILDREN.
[ Judy ] $19 A MONTH
IS LESS THAN A DOLLAR A DAY.
IT'S SUCH A LITTLE BIT,
THAT DOES SUCH A LOT!
[ Male Announcer ] BECOMING
A MONTHLY PARTNER IN HOPE
COULD BE ONE OF THE MOST
MEANINGFUL THINGS YOU EVER DO,
BUT IF YOUR
CIRCUMSTANCES CHANGE,
YOU CAN CANCEL AT ANY TIME
AND KNOW
YOU'VE MADE A DIFFERENCE.
PLEASE -- CHILDREN'S LIVES
DEPEND ON YOU.
CALL NOW AND BECOME A ST. JUDE
PARTNER IN HOPE TODAY.
♪
AS A PARENT, YOU DO EVERYTHING
TO PROTECT YOUR CHILD FROM HARM.
BUT HOW DO YOU PROTECT
YOUR CHILD FROM BRAIN CANCER?
ESPECIALLY ONE OF THE RAREST
AND MOST DEADLY OF ALL.
I CAN'T IMAGINE SOMETHING
SO HEARTBREAKING.
BUT WHEN PETER'S FAMILY
CAME THROUGH THE DOORS
OF ST. JUDE FACING THIS CRISIS,
THE FIRST THING THEY WERE GIVEN
WAS WHAT THEY NEEDED MOST.
HOPE.
PETER'S MOM AND DAD
WERE CLINGING TO HOPE
THE NIGHT THEY WALKED
THROUGH THE DOORS OF ST. JUDE,
KNOWING THEIR 2-YEAR-OLD SON
HAD A BRAIN TUMOR.
IT WAS DEFINITELY ONE
OF THE WORST NIGHTS OF MY LIFE.
PETE'S TUMOR
WAS EXTREMELY RARE --
KIND OF RAREST OF THE RARE.
[ Betty ]
PETE HAS PINEOBLASTOMA,
A FAST-GROWING CANCER
LOCATED IN THE THIRD VENTRICLE
OF HIS BRAIN.
[ Kelly ]
IT WAS A HUGE SHOCK.
MY SHOCK TURNED INTO, "WHAT ARE
WE GONNA DO ABOUT THIS?"
[ Betty ] NEUROSURGEONS
REMOVED 95% OF PETE'S TUMOR.
AND THEN OUR DOCTORS
AND SCIENTISTS WENT TO WORK
TO SHRINK THE REMAINING TUMOR
AND KEEP IT FROM COMING BACK.
THIS IS AN EXTREMELY RARE TUMOR,
EXTREMELY AGGRESSIVE TUMOR,
OKAY?
A TUMOR THAT CAN SPREAD
TO OTHER PLACES.
WE HAVE MADE
SIGNIFICANT IMPROVEMENT
IN THE RESULTS OF THERAPY,
AND THE WAY TO APPROACH
THESE TUMORS STEP BY STEP.
[ Kelly ] HE WILL HAVE 20 WEEKS
OF CHEMOTHERAPY,
AND THEN HE WILL HAVE 6 WEEKS
OF CONFORMAL RADIATION
AND THEN ANOTHER 20 WEEKS
OF CHEMO.
I WANT TO READ BOOK,
DADA.
[ Jeff ]
YOU WANT TO READ A BOOK?
WHAT DOES A DINOSAUR
SOUND LIKE?
[ ROARS ]
THAT'S RIGHT.
[ Jeff ] I TRY TO TAKE IT
ONE DAY AT A TIME.
I TRY NOT TO THINK
ONE WAY OR THE OTHER
WHAT HIS OUTCOME'S GONNA BE.
I TRY NOT TO THINK
THAT FAR AHEAD.
I FEEL LIKE MY JOB NOW
IS JUST TO SPEND AS MUCH TIME
WITH MY SON AS POSSIBLE.
SLIDE THAT IN THERE.
[ Kelly ]
WE HAVE SOMETHING TO BELIEVE IN.
MIRACLES DO HAPPEN HERE.
IT'S AN AMAZING,
WONDERFUL PLACE TO BE.
GIVE ME A HIGH FIVE!
ALL RIGHT!
GOOD JOB.
[ Kelly ]
HE IS A GREAT LITTLE PATIENT.
HE SEES THE DOCTORS COME IN,
AND HE LIFTS UP HIS SHIRT
SO THAT THEY CAN LISTEN
TO HIS HEART.
HE IS QUITE A CHARACTER.
PETE IS QUITE A CHARACTER.
ONE CAN ONLY FEEL HONORED
IN PARTICIPATING IN HIS CARE.
STILL SLEEPY?
[ Jeff ]
WELL, TODAY HE'S GETTING
ANOTHER DOSE OF RADIATION.
[ Dr. Bikhazi ] BASICALLY,
YOU WANT TO REDUCE DAMAGE
TO AREAS THAT DON'T HAVE TUMORS.
THESE MACHINES CAN PINPOINT
WHERE THE RADIATION HAS TO GO.
IT'S A TRUE BLESSING TO BE ABLE
TO TAKE CARE OF THESE CHILDREN
AND PROVIDE THEM WITH
THE BEST AVAILABLE TECHNOLOGY.
♪
[ Jeff ] WE WERE GIVEN A BREAK
IN PETER'S TREATMENT,
SO WE WERE ABLE TO COME HOME
FOR THREE WEEKS,
AND IT KIND OF REMINDS US
HOW MUCH WE REALLY MISS HOME.
[ Kelly ] WE WENT ON THE SWINGS
AND DID THE SLIDE A BIT,
AND THEN WE WALKED DOWN
TO THE DUCK POND.
WHILE PETE IS OUT HERE
RUNNING AROUND ON THE GRASS,
WE HAVE RESEARCHERS
BACK AT ST. JUDE
HELPING TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT STEPS TO TAKE NEXT
AND HOW TO MAKE HIM BETTER.
[ Jeff ]
YOU TRY TO STAY POSITIVE,
BUT YOU KIND OF HAVE TO FACE
THE REALITY OF THE SITUATION.
THE ODDS ARE STACKED
AGAINST HIM.
GRAB IT DOWN
ON THE STEM DOWN HERE.
TAKE IT.
TAKE IT FOR MAMA.
[ Jeff ] WE WILL FIGHT,
AND WE'LL DO EVERYTHING WE CAN
TO KEEP HIM HERE.
YOU KNOW, HE'S MY LITTLE BOY,
AND I LOVE HIM TO PIECES.
[ babbling ]
[ Jeff ] HOW DO YOU KEEP YOUR
KID SAFE FROM A BRAIN TUMOR?
I CAN'T PROTECT HIM FROM THAT.
ALL I CAN DO IS GIVE HIM
THE BEST TREATMENT AVAILABLE.
[ Kelly ]
WE DIDN'T HAVE, REALLY,
ANY HOPE
UNTIL WE CAME TO ST. JUDE.
YOU CAN'T GIVE UP,
AND ST. JUDE AND ALL THE
DOCTORS AND NURSES --
THEY DON'T GIVE UP.
BYE.
[ Jeff ] YOU REALLY DON'T KNOW
HOW MANY MORE TIMES
THEY HAVE TO PLAY TOGETHER.
MAKES ME KIND OF UPSET
TO THINK ABOUT IT.
HIS TIME HERE WITH US
MAY BE LIMITED,
SO, YOU KNOW, WE HAVE TO LIVE
IN THE MOMENT --
LIVE IT TO THE FULLEST
WHILE WE CAN.
♪
TODAY PETER IS IN REMISSION.
HE'S DOING WHAT KIDS DO BEST --
PLAYING.
GOING TO SCHOOL.
LOVING HIS FAMILY.
BUT IF HIS CANCER RETURNS
IT WILL MOST LIKELY
SPREAD QUICKLY.
ST. JUDE RESEARCHERS
HAVE NOT YET FOUND THE CURE
THAT WILL STOP
RECURRENT PINEOBLASTOMA.
BUT WE'LL NEVER GIVE UP TRYING.
AND I KNOW YOU WON'T, EITHER.
JOIN ME.
HELP SAVE KIDS LIKE PETER.
CALL NOW, AND BECOME A ST. JUDE
PARTNER IN HOPE TODAY.
♪
WHENEVER I MEET CHILDREN
FIGHTING CANCER,
I COME AWAY INSPIRED --
AND TRULY HUMBLED --
BY THEIR BRAVERY
AND THEIR DETERMINATION.
AND I WANT TO DO
EVERYTHING I CAN
TO HELP ST. JUDE
SAVE THEIR LIVES.
HERE'S A GREAT LITTLE FIGHTER
NAMED COLIN.
[ laughing ]
♪
[ Gloria ]
WHEN COLIN WAS JUST 2 YEARS OLD,
HE DEVELOPED CANCER
OF THE CENTRAL NERVOUS SYSTEM.
HE HAD AN EPENDYMOMA TUMOR
ON THE FOURTH VENTRICLE
OF HIS BRAIN
THAT EXTENDED DOWN
ONTO HIS SPINE.
THE TUMOR WAS SO MASSIVE,
IT COMPRESSED MANY OF THE NERVES
THAT CONTROLLED SWALLOWING,
SPEECH.
AND ALL YOU CAN THINK OF IS,
HOW COULD THIS BEAUTIFUL CHILD
BE ONE WHO'S AFFLICTED
WITH A TUMOR?
[ Gloria ] DOCTORS MOVED QUICKLY
TO REMOVE THE TUMOR,
AND COLIN WAS REFERRED
TO ST. JUDE CHILDREN'S
RESEARCH HOSPITAL.
[ Ian ]
WE WEREN'T ABLE TO TELL
WHETHER OR NOT
HE WOULD WALK AGAIN,
WHETHER HE WOULD
BE ABLE TO SWALLOW
AND EVEN OPEN HIS MOUTH
OR MOVE HIS TONGUE.
1, 2, 3.
[ Gloria ] ST. JUDE
DOCTORS AND SCIENTISTS
ARE PART
OF A UNIQUE CLINICAL TRIAL
DESIGNED TO SAVE THE LIVES
OF CHILDREN
STRICKEN WITH THIS RARE DISEASE.
HI, COLIN!
TALK TO ME, BUDDY.
[ Ian ] ST. JUDE IS EVERYTHING
TO ME RIGHT NOW,
BECAUSE THEY'VE GIVEN US HOPE.
IS THAT DADDY?
ARE YOU POINTING AT DADDY?
I CAN'T EVEN COUNT
HOW MANY TIMES
WHERE WE FELT LIKE HE MIGHT NOT
PULL THROUGH THE DAY.
THERE HAVE BEEN MANY
OF THOSE DAYS.
[ Gloria ] TREATMENT FOR COLIN
INCLUDES A COMBINATION
OF CHEMOTHERAPY AND RADIATION
DESIGNED TO SHRINK AND KILL
ALL TRACES OF THE TUMOR.
HAVING THE DISEASE
HAS TAKEN ITS TOLL ON COLIN.
[ Ian ] COLIN CAN'T TALK,
SO MOST OF THE COMMUNICATION
IS WITH OUR EYES.
THAT'S PRETTY POWERFUL.
WHERE'S YOUR NOSE?
IS THAT YOUR NOSE? YEAH?
HE'S TRAPPED,
BUT HE'S EMERGING.
I SEE THAT THERE'S A PART OF HIM
THAT'S STILL
IN HIS MIND VERY ACTIVE,
AND WANTING TO COME OUT.
DO YOU SEE THE BUTTERFLY
ON THERE?
YEAH? DO YOU LIKE
MARISSA'S RAINBOW?
COLIN, BLOW A KISS.
[ Tamiko ] MWAH!
HE'S AN AMAZING CHILD.
HE'S CHARMING, PLAYFUL.
HE'S A VERY DETERMINED CHILD.
IF I SEIZE UPON ENJOYING EVERY
POSSIBLE MOMENT I CAN WITH HIM,
AND LOOKING FORWARD
TO TINY LITTLE VICTORIES,
IF WE CAN SHARE SOME HAPPINESS,
THEN THAT CAN NEVER
BE TAKEN AWAY.
GOOD JOB!
HE'S GONE
FROM PARTIAL PARALYSIS,
TO HAVING MULTIPLE
BRAIN SURGERIES,
WONDERING IF HE'S EVER
GONNA MOVE AGAIN,
TO A CHILD WHO'S LIKE
THAT LITTLE ENGINE
WHO JUST KEEPS PUSHING FORWARD,
WHO JUST REFUSES TO QUIT.
[ laughter ]
GOOD JOB!
[ Gloria ]
WHILE EVERYONE IS EXCITED
ABOUT COLIN'S LITTLE VICTORIES
IN PHYSICAL THERAPY,
THE BATTLE TO KILL THE TUMOR
AND SAVE HIS LIFE CONTINUES.
TODAY COLIN HAD AN MRI,
AND HIS PARENTS WAIT ANXIOUSLY
FOR THE RESULTS.
IT'S GONNA TELL US IF THE CHEMO
HAS MADE THE TUMOR SHRINK.
WITH EPENDYMOMA, IT'S A VERY
PERSISTENT TYPE OF TUMOR,
AND IF YOU LEAVE ANY REMNANTS,
IT HAS SUCH A HIGH CHANCE
OF COMING BACK.
♪
[ Gloria ] THE MRI CONFIRMS THAT
THE TUMOR HAS GOTTEN SMALLER.
SO, THIS IS GOOD.
[ Gloria ]
BUT THERE'S MORE GOOD NEWS,
AS COLIN REACHES
AN IMPORTANT MILESTONE.
[ Tamiko ] HE HAS STARTED
REALLY TRYING TO TALK.
MAMA!
IT'S VERY EXCITING.
HE WILL SOMETIMES
SPONTANEOUSLY USE WORDS
I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW THAT HE KNEW.
WHAT IS THIS?
BUG.
[ Ian ] HE'S BACK!
I MEAN, THAT BOY IS BACK!
KEEP GOING.
GOT TO STAND UP ALL THE WAY.
♪
[ Gloria ] COLIN CONTINUES
TO SURPRISE EVERYONE
AS HE TAKES HIS FIRST
TENTATIVE STEPS
SINCE THE TUMOR WAS REMOVED.
[ Tamiko ] TO BE AT THIS POINT
WHERE WE HAVE OUR SON BACK,
IS AMAZING.
YOU CAN DO IT.
THIS IS REALLY THE KID THAT
WE KNEW BEFORE ALL THIS STARTED.
[ cheering ]
GOOD JOB!
♪
[ Ian ] HE HAS MADE
A TREMENDOUS RECOVERY.
IT'S POSSIBLE THERE'S
A REMNANT OF THE TUMOR
LEFT ON THE BRAINSTEM.
THAT LAST LITTLE BIT IS
A STUBBORN LITTLE BIT.
WE HAVE SOME
OF THE HARDEST DECISIONS
YOU COULD EVER IMAGINE
ON THE HORIZON.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE ELSE IN THE
WORLD WE COULD GET THIS CARE.
♪
[ Gloria ]
YOU CAN SEE WHY BRAIN TUMORS
ARE SO TERRIFYING
FOR A FAMILY TO ENDURE.
AND TRAGICALLY,
THEY'RE THE SECOND MOST COMMON
FORM OF CHILDHOOD CANCER,
AFTER LEUKEMIA.
BUT FOR A CHILD
FACING THAT BATTLE,
THERE'S NO PLACE LIKE ST. JUDE.
THEY'VE TREATED CHILDREN
FROM ALL OVER,
NEVER TURNING ANYONE AWAY
BECAUSE OF A FAMILY'S
INABILITY TO PAY.
EVEN PROVIDING TRANSPORTATION.
FOOD. HOUSING.
AND ALWAYS -- HOPE.
BUT THEY CAN ONLY DO IT
WITH YOUR HELP.
PLEASE, JOIN US AS A ST. JUDE
PARTNER IN HOPE.
[ Male Announcer ]
CALL RIGHT NOW
AND BECOME A ST. JUDE
PARTNER IN HOPE.
YOUR COMMITMENT OF $19 A MONTH
WILL HELP
SAVE CHILDREN'S LIVES.
WE TREAT CHILDREN FROM ALL
50 STATES AND AROUND THE WORLD.
AND FOR MANY OF THEM,
ST. JUDE CHILDREN'S RESEARCH
HOSPITAL IS THEIR ONLY HOPE.
WHEN A FAMILY
COMES THROUGH THE DOORS HERE,
THE FIRST THING WE WANT TO DO
IS GIVE THEM HOPE.
AND THE FIRST THING WE SAY IS,
"WE'RE GONNA DO EVERYTHING
WE CAN TO SAVE YOUR CHILD."
[ Male Announcer ] ST. JUDE
DEPENDS ON YOUR SUPPORT
FOR THE RESEARCH AND TREATMENTS
THESE CHILDREN NEED TODAY.
NO CHILD IS EVER TURNED AWAY
BECAUSE OF THE FAMILY'S
INABILITY TO PAY.
THAT'S WHY YOUR CALL --
RIGHT NOW -- IS SO IMPORTANT.
[ Cathy ]
UNTIL THOSE BEDS ARE EMPTY,
WE HAVE TO KEEP GIVING
TO ST. JUDE.
IT'S AN INVESTMENT
IN A CHILD'S FUTURE.
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR RESEARCH BREAKTHROUGHS
HAVE HELPED MORE THAN TRIPLE
THE SURVIVAL RATE
FOR CHILDHOOD CANCERS.
ST. JUDE EVEN COVERS
THE COST OF TRAVEL,
FOOD AND HOUSING
FOR A PARENT AND CHILD.
IT'S THE VERY FIRST
PEDIATRIC INSTITUTION
EVER TO PUT RESEARCH
AND TREATMENT UNDER ONE ROOF.
AND EVERY DISCOVERY MADE
AT ST. JUDE
IS SHARED FREELY WITH DOCTORS
AND SCIENTISTS WORLDWIDE.
CALL NOW AND BECOME
A ST. JUDE PARTNER IN HOPE.
JUST $19 A MONTH
WILL HELP FIND THE CURES
TO SAVE CHILDREN'S LIVES.
GOD BLESS OUR PARTNERS IN HOPE.
WE'D BE LOST WITHOUT THEM.
EVERY SINGLE GIFT MEANS HELP
FOR ANOTHER CHILD.
[ Male Announcer ] CALL NOW
AND JOIN THOUSANDS OF AMERICANS
WHO ARE ST. JUDE PARTNERS
IN HOPE
WITH YOUR COMMITMENT
OF JUST $19 A MONTH.
IF YOU PREFER -- A GENEROUS
GIFT OF ANY SIZE RIGHT NOW
WILL HELP SAVE
CHILDREN'S LIVES.
YOU CAN EVEN MAKE YOUR PAYMENTS
AUTOMATICALLY
USING YOUR DEBIT
OR CREDIT CARD.
IT'S CONVENIENT,
AND IT SAVES MONEY SO MORE
GOES DIRECTLY TO THE KIDS.
EACH AND EVERY GIFT
IS INCREDIBLY IMPORTANT.
[ Male Announcer ] PLEASE --
THE CHILDREN
ARE COUNTING ON YOU.
CALL NOW AND BECOME A
ST. JUDE PARTNER IN HOPE TODAY.
♪
ONE OF THE MOST AMAZING THINGS
ABOUT ST. JUDE
IS THE LOVE THEY GIVE
TO EVERY CHILD.
THEY MAY BE FIGHTING
FOR THEIR LIVES,
BUT THEY CAN ALSO HAVE FUN --
JUST BEING KIDS.
JUST WATCH DAEGEN.
BUT HE DOES.
♪
HEY!
[ Woman ] HELLO.
IT'S ACUTE MYELOID LEUKEMIA,
THE DEADLIEST LEUKEMIA
A CHILD CAN GET.
WITH 4-YEAR-OLD DAEGEN
AND YOU'RE LIABLE TO HAVE A HARD
TIME KEEPING UP WITH HIM.
ON YOUR MARK, GET SET, GO!
[ Tom ] HE NOT ONLY HAS
AN ACTIVE IMAGINATION,
HE NEVER SEEMS
TO RUN OUT OF ENERGY.
MOM, WATCH.
[ Tom ] IT'S HARD
TO BELIEVE HE HAS CANCER,
BUT HE DOES.
♪
HEY!
[ Woman ] HELLO.
IT'S ACUTE MYELOID LEUKEMIA,
THE DEADLIEST LEUKEMIA
A CHILD CAN GET.
DAEGEN WAS FIRST TREATED
IN HIS HOMETOWN IN KANSAS.
THEY GOT DAEGEN INTO REMISSION
AND GAVE HIM
A BONE-MARROW TRANSPLANT.
BUT HE RELAPSED.
IT WAS THEN
THAT HIS PARENTS TURNED
TO ST. JUDE CHILDREN'S
RESEARCH HOSPITAL FOR HELP.
[ Lance ] THERE YOU GO.
WHEN YOU REALIZE THAT YOUR CHILD
MAY NOT BE HERE TOMORROW,
THEN YOU KIND OF HAVE
A DIFFERENT PERSPECTIVE
ON WHAT TODAY MEANS.
AND IT HAS GIVEN, YOU KNOW,
HOPE TO OUR FAMILY
THAT MAYBE DAEGEN WILL MAKE IT.
♪
HE'S SICK,
BUT YOU WOULD NEVER KNOW IT.
HE ACTS LIKE A NORMAL CHILD,
AND HE KNOWS HE HAS CANCER.
HE KNOWS HE'S SICK.
AH. NICE, WARM BLANKET.
AND STILL HE GETS UP
EVERY DAY HAPPY,
RUNNING AROUND, FULL OF ENERGY.
OH, LOOK AT THAT ONE.
HE LIKES ME.
MOMMY, HERE'S THE PEOPLE.
[ Tom ]
THE MEDICAL TEAM AT ST. JUDE
WAS ABLE TO GET DAEGEN
INTO A SECOND REMISSION.
LET'S PLAY, MAMA.
OKAY.
AND ONCE AGAIN, HE IS GOING TO
RECEIVE A BONE-MARROW TRANSPLANT
THAT WILL HOPEFULLY
KEEP HIM IN REMISSION
AND LEAD TO A CURE.
EVERYTHING'S READY.
[ Tom ] THIS TRANSPLANT
IS DIFFERENT THAN BEFORE.
ST. JUDE PIONEERED A TECHNIQUE
THAT LETS PARENTS
WHO ARE ONLY A PARTIAL MATCH
BE A DONOR FOR THEIR CHILD --
IN THIS CASE, DAEGEN'S DAD.
IT'S CALLED
A HAPLO-IDENTICAL TRANSPLANT,
AND IT HOLDS NEW PROMISE
FOR KIDS LIKE DAEGEN.
THEY ARE FINDING CURES,
AND THEY'RE MAKING IMPROVEMENTS,
AND THEY'RE DOING RESEARCH
AND DOING EXPERIMENTS
THAT NO OTHER HOSPITAL IS DOING.
[ Daegen ] RED.
[ Janelle ] YES.
YELLOW. BLUE.
ALL RIGHT!
[ Tom ]
IT'S BEEN OVER SIX MONTHS
SINCE DAEGEN'S TRANSPLANT.
HE'S HERE THIS WEEK
FOR HIS REGULAR CHECKUP
TO MAKE SURE
HE'S STILL CANCER FREE.
BUT THERE'S SOMETHING
THAT HAS HIS MOTHER WORRIED.
[ Janelle ]
DAEGEN WAS COMPLAINING
ABOUT HIS LEG HURTING HIM,
AND THAT HAS BEEN A TRADEMARK
IN TERMS
OF WHEN HE WAS FIRST DIAGNOSED
AND THEN WHEN HE RELAPSED.
IF HE CONTINUES
TO COMPLAIN ABOUT LEG PAIN,
THEN I'M GONNA BE
VERY CONCERNED,
BECAUSE THEN
HE COULD BE RELAPSING.
♪
[ Tom ] SAMPLES ARE BEING TAKEN
OF DAEGEN'S BONE MARROW.
IT'S AN EXTREMELY STRESSFUL TIME
FOR DAEGEN'S PARENTS
AND THE TEAM AT ST. JUDE,
BECAUSE THEY'VE RUN
OUT OF OPTIONS.
IF THE TRANSPLANT HASN'T WORKED,
THERE IS NOTHING ELSE
THAT CAN BE DONE TO SAVE HIM.
♪
24 HOURS LATER, TEST RESULTS
CONFIRM EVERYONE'S WORST FEAR.
♪
THE CANCER IS BACK.
DAEGEN HAS RELAPSED.
HIS PARENTS DECIDE
TO TAKE HIM HOME,
WHERE HE WILL SPEND
HIS FINAL DAYS.
[ All ]
♪ HAPPY BIRTHDAY TO YOU
[ Tom ] FRIENDS AND FAMILY
GATHER FOR A BIRTHDAY PARTY.
[ All ]
♪ ...TO YOU
♪ HAPPY BIRTHDAY...
[ Tom ] DAEGEN WOULD HAVE BEEN
5 YEARS OLD TODAY.
♪
[ Janelle ]
WE TALKED TO HIM VERY OPENLY
ABOUT GOING TO BE AN ANGEL
AND GOING TO BE IN HEAVEN.
HE GOT REALLY SAD ONE DAY
BECAUSE HE THOUGHT,
"HOW IS MY BLANKET AND MY TRAINS
GOING TO BE UP THERE?"
[ Lance ]
THE DAY BEFORE HE PASSED AWAY,
I TOLD DAEGEN THAT WE LOVED HIM,
THAT MOMMY AND DADDY
WERE IN THE ROOM WITH HIM.
HE TOOK OUR HANDS.
AT THIS POINT,
HE WAS NO LONGER TALKING.
HE WASN'T MOVING.
HE WASN'T EVEN OPENING HIS EYES.
BUT HE TOOK OUR HANDS
AND SQUEEZED THEM WITH HIS.
AND THEN HE PULLED THEM CLOSER,
ABOVE HIS HEART.
I BELIEVE SOMEDAY ST. JUDE
WILLLL FIND THE MAGICAL CURE
THAT TREATS PEDIATRIC A.M.L.
I'M NOT GONNA GIVE UP HOPE.
NOW MORE THAN EVER, THE RESEARCH
IS SO IMPORTANT TO US.
THEY GAVE US 10 MONTHS
OF A LIFE WITH OUR SON
THAT WE WOULDN'T HAVE HAD.
♪
LANCE AND I WILL CONTINUE,
FOR THE REST OF OUR LIVES,
TO RAISE MONEY FOR ST. JUDE
TO FIND A CURE.
♪
TRSURED MEMORIES
OF AN ANGEL LIKE DAEGEN.
THEY INSPIRE US --
AND MOTIVATE THE DOCTORS
AND SCIENTISTS AND RESEARCHERS
AT ST. JUDE TO DOUBLE
THEIR EFFORTS TO FIND CURES
SO THAT CHILDREN LIKE DAEGEN
DON'T HAVE TO DIE.
BUT ST. JUDE DEPENDS ON YOU
TO HELP MAKE THAT HAPPEN.
PLEASE. CALL TODAY AND BECOME
A PARTNER IN HOPE RIGHT NOW.
♪
AT ST. JUDE,
NO CHILD IS EVER TURNED AWAY
BECAUSE OF THE FAMILY'S
INABILITY TO PAY.
THAT'S HOW IMPORTANT
EVERY YOUNG LIFE IS TO US.
ST. JUDE COVERS
ALL THE TREATMENTS,
WHATEVER IS NEEDED
TO HELP SAVE A CHILD'S LIFE.
AND WE ALSO PAY FOR TRAVEL,
MEALS, AND HOUSING
FOR A CHILD AND A PARENT.
FOR ARIANNA,
THAT KIND OF SUPPORT IS VITAL,
BECAUSE SHE'S FIGHTING
A VERY AGGRESSIVE BRAIN CANCER.
ENRIQUE WAS STATIONED
IN JAPAN WITH THE U.S. NAVY,
WHEN HIS DAUGHTER ARIANNA
WAS BORN.
HE CALLED HER
HIS "LITTLE PRINCESS."
BUT WHEN SHE WAS 2 YEARS OLD
SHE STARTED HAVING CONVULSIONS.
A SERIES OF TESTS REVEALED
A MASS IN ARIANNA'S BRAIN.
THE FAMILY WAS FLOWN BACK TO THE
UNITED STATES FOR MORE TESTS.
THEY WERE
IN THEIR DOCTOR'S OFFICE
WHEN THEY GOT THE DIAGNOSIS.
MY DAUGHTER WAS DIAGNOSED WITH
ATYPICAL TERATOID
RHABDOID TUMOR, ATRT.
HE SAID, "I'M SORRY TO BE
THE ONE TO TELL YOU THIS.
IT'S VERY RARE, AND IT'S GONNA
BE VERY DIFFICULT TO TREAT."
THEY GAVE HER 16 MONTHS TO LIVE.
HE SAYS, "I WOULD JUST TAKE HER
HOME AND MAKE HER COMFORTABLE.
AND MAKE A LOT OF MEMORIES."
[ Marlo ] UNWILLING TO ACCEPT
THIS DEATH SENTENCE,
ENRIQUE AND LETICIA SPENT HOURS
ON THE INTERNET
RESEARCHING ATRT
AND THE WORK BEING DONE
BY DR. AMAR GAJJAR
AT ST. JUDE CHILDREN'S
RESEARCH HOSPITAL.
THEY ASKED THEIR DOCTOR
TO REFER ARIANNA TO ST. JUDE,
AND THE VERY NEXT DAY,
LETICIA GOT THE PHONE CALL
THAT SHE HAD BEEN PRAYING FOR.
AND HE SAID "THIS IS DR. GAJJAR
FROM ST. JUDE."
AND I -- THE PHONE DROPPED.
AND MY HUSBAND WAS LIKE,
"WHAT'S WRONG?"
AND I WAS LIKE, "IT'S..."
I FIR-- I COULDN'T EVEN TALK
AT FIRST,
AND I WAS LIKE, "IT'S --
DR. GAJJAR IS ON THE PHONE!"
[ Marlo ] 10 HOURS LATER,
ARIANNA WAS ADMITTED
AS A PATIENT AT ST. JUDE.
♪
CURRENTLY THERE IS NO CURE
FOR ATRT,
BUT ST. JUDE HAS DEVELOPED
A PROTOCOL
THAT COMBINES CHEMOTHERAPY
AND RADIATION
THAT WILL HOPEFULLY
KEEP ARIANNA ALIVE
WHILE RESEARCHERS AT ST. JUDE
SEARCH FOR A CURE.
[ monitor beeping ]
[ Leticia ] SHE HAS COMPLETED
31 RADIATION TREATMENTS,
AND HAS DONE GREAT.
WE WAIT THREE WEEKS
FOR THE NEXT ROUND OF CHEMO.
[ babbling ]
[ Leticia ]
ANA'S A CHARACTER.
SHE IS YOUR NEXT LITTLE ACTRESS.
SHE IS A PRINCESS
EVERY DAY OF THE WEEK.
SHE RUNS TO HER CLOSET.
SHE PICKS OUT A NEW OUTFIT.
NO MATTER HOW BAD YOUR DAY IS,
SHE WILL MAKE IT BETTER.
COME ON, MOMMY.
PLAY WITH ME. PLAY WITH ME.
[ monitor beeping ]
TODAY THEY'RE DOING AN MRI.
THEY'RE DOING AN EKG,
AND THEY'RE DOING A --
A SPINAL TAP.
A LUMBAR PUNCTURE IS TO MAKE
SURE THERE'S NO CANCER CELLS,
AND, UH, THE MRI IS TO SEE
HOW MUCH THE RADIATION HELPED.
[ Marlo ]
TODAY'S RESULTS ARE CRITICAL.
IF THE TUMOR HAS GROWN,
THERE ARE FEW OPTIONS LEFT
FOR ARIANNA.
HER CHANCES FOR SURVIVAL
WOULD BE GREATLY REDUCED.
DR. GAJJAR ARRIVES
WITH THE RESULTS.
OKAY, THE SCANS ARE VERY GOOD.
OKAY!
[ babbling ]
YOU'RE GOOD! YOU'RE GOOD,
YOU'RE GOOD, YOU'RE GOOD!
[ Marlo ] WHILE THERE IS A LOT
TO BE GRATEFUL FOR,
A NEW ISSUE HAS SURFACED THAT
HAS ARIANNA'S PARENTS WORRIED.
[ Leticia ] I REMEMBER JUST
SEEING HOW WITHDRAWN SHE WAS,
AND HOW UNCOMFORTABLE SHE WAS
WITH ALL THE LITTLE GIRLS.
THERE WAS FOUR,
AND THEY ALL HAD HAIR.
A COUPLE DAYS LATER,
MY COUSIN CAME INTO TOWN.
AND SHE TOOK A PICTURE
OF ARIANNA.
AND SHE LOOKED AT HER
AND SHE SAID, "LOOK IT!"
SHE'S LIKE,
"YOU LOOK SO PRETTY."
AND SHE WENT TO SHOW HER
THE PICTURE.
AND ANA LOOKED AT HER AND SAID,
"THAT'S NOT PRETTY.
I DON'T HAVE HAIR."
THAT NIGHT WE CAME HOME.
I WENT INTO MY BEDROOM.
I PUT MY HAIR IN A PONYTAIL,
AND I JUST CUT IT OFF.
♪
IN THE MORNING
SHE JUST LOOKED UP AT ME
LIKE A DEER IN HEADLIGHTS.
AND I SAID, "WHAT'S THE MATTER?"
AND SHE SAID,
"WHERE'D YOUR HAIR GO?"
I SAID, "WELL,
NOW I'M BEAUTIFUL LIKE YOU."
AND SHE SAID,
"YOU'RE THE BEST MAMA EVER!"
WHAT'S SHE GONNA DO?
"SHE WAS A ROYAL PRINCESS."
SHE SAID, "THANK YOU GUYS
FOR MAKING ME FEEL BETTER."
[ Marlo ] FINALLY, THE DAY
EVERYONE HAS BEEN WAITING FOR...
[ cheering ]
[ indistinct singing ]
[ Marlo ]
...ARIANNA'S LAST DAY
OF CHEMOTHERAPY.
[ Leticia ] WE HAD A PARTY FIT
FOR A PRINCESS.
THEY SING
A "NO MORE CHEMO" SONG.
[ cheering ]
AND THE SMILE ON HER FACE!
UH! THE SMILE.
I THOUGHT I WAS GONNA
BURY MY CHILD.
I THOUGHT SHE WAS GONNA DIE.
WHAT PEOPLE NEED TO REALIZE IS,
IT DOESN'T HAPPEN
TO OTHER PEOPLE.
IT CAN HAPPEN TO YOU.
IT CAN HAPPEN
TO YOUR BEST FRIEND.
IT CAN HAPPEN TO YOUR SISTER.
IT CAN HAPPEN
TO ANYBODY THAT YOU LOVE.
I WANNA SAY TO PLEASE
BECOME A PARTNER IN HOPE,
BECAUSE THERE'S KIDS OUT THERE
THAT NEED YOU.
♪
I LOVE YOU, DAD!
[ Male Announcer ] YOU CAN
HELP SAVE A CHILD'S LIFE.
CALL RIGHT NOW AND BECOME
A ST. JUDE PARTNER IN HOPE.
JUST $19 A MONTH
WILL HELP PROVIDE
BREAKTHROUGH RESEARCH,
TREATMENTS AND CURES.
WE HELP CHILDREN FROM ALL
50 STATES AND AROUND THE WORLD.
AND FOR MANY OF THEM,
ST. JUDE CHILDREN'S RESEARCH
HOSPITAL IS THEIR ONLY HOPE.
IT TAKES ALL OF US
TO MAKE THIS HAPPEN --
THE DOCTORS, THE SCIENTISTS,
AND THE PARTNERS IN HOPE.
[ Male Announcer ] ST. JUDE
CHILDREN'S RESEARCH HOSPITAL
BEGAN AS THE DREAM OF ONE MAN,
DANNY THOMAS.
MY FATHER'S DREAM
SIMPLY WAS THAT
NO CHILD SHOULD DIE
IN THE DAWN OF LIFE
AND THAT'S WHAT
WE'RE ALL STILL WORKING TOWARD.
[ Gail ] PEOPLE THINK,
"IF I DON'T HAVE A LOT TO GIVE,
THEN WHAT I GIVE
ISN'T GOING TO MATTER.
IT MATTERS.
EVERY SINGLE PENNY MATTERS.
THAT LITTLE PART
THAT YOU'RE PLAYING,
YOU KNOW, IS COMBINED
WITH EVERYBODY ELSE.
AND IT HELPS
TO TRULY MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR RESEARCH BREAKTHROUGHS
HAVE HELPED MORE THAN TRIPLE
THE SURVIVAL RATE
FOR CHILDHOOD CANCERS.
WHEN ST. JUDE OPENED
ONLY 4 OUT OF 100 CHILDREN
SURVIVED THE MOST COMMON
CHILDHOOD CANCER.
TODAY, 94% OF KIDS
WITH THAT DISEASE
GET TO GO HOME
AND KEEP GROWING.
NO CHILD IS EVER TURNED AWAY
FOR A FAMILY'S
INABILITY TO PAY.
CALL NOW AND BECOME
A ST. JUDE PARTNER IN HOPE.
JUST $19 A MONTH
WILL HELP FIND THE CURES
TO SAVE CHILDREN'S LIVES.
CALL NOW AND JOIN
THOUSANDS OF AMERICANS
WHO ARE ST. JUDE PARTNERS
IN HOPE
WITH YOUR COMMITMENT
OF JUST $19 A MONTH.
IF YOU PREFER -- A GENEROUS
GIFT OF ANY SIZE RIGHT NOW
WILL HELP SAVE
CHILDREN'S LIVES.
YOU CAN EVEN MAKE YOUR PAYMENTS
AUTOMATICALLY
USING YOUR DEBIT
OR CREDIT CARD.
IT SAVES MONEY
SO MORE OF YOUR DONATION
GOES DIRECTLY TO HELP CHILDREN.
EVERY DIME COUNTS
AND IT MAKES A DIFFERENCE.
THERE'S NOT A GREATER PLACE
IN THE WORLD,
AS FAR AS I'M CONCERNED,
TO SEND YOUR MONEY TO.
[ Male Announcer ] BECOMING
A MONTHLY PARTNER IN HOPE
COULD BE ONE OF THE MOST
MEANINGFUL THINGS YOU EVER DO,
BUT IF YOUR
CIRCUMSTANCES CHANGE,
YOU CAN CANCEL AT ANY TIME
AND KNOW
YOU'VE MADE A DIFFERENCE.
PLEASE -- CHILDREN'S LIVES
DEPEND ON YOU.
CALL NOW AND BECOME A ST. JUDE
PARTNER IN HOPE TODAY.
♪
EVERY DAY THERE ARE
THOUSANDS OF CHILDREN
FIGHTING FOR THEIR LIVES
WITH ST. JUDE BY THEIR SIDES.
WHAT IF ONE OF THEM
WAS YOUR CHILD?
YOU'D DO EVERYTHING YOU COULD
TO HELP SAVE THEIR LIFE.
THAT'S WHY IT'S SO IMPORTANT
TO BECOME A ST. JUDE
PARTNER IN HOPE.
YOU CAN HELP FIND CURES
AND SAVE LIVES.
ALL IT TAKES
IS A QUICK PHONE CALL.
JOIN US TODAY.
TOGETHER,
WE CAN WORK TOWARD THE DAY
WHEN CHILDREN WITH CANCER
CAN ALL GO HOME
WITH THEIR MOMS AND DADS --
HEALTHY, HOPEFUL,
AND FULL OF LIFE.
I THOUGHT I WAS GONNA
BURY MY CHILD.
I THOUGHT SHE WAS GONNA DIE.
YOU NEVER THINK THAT YOUR CHILD
WILL HAVE CANCER.
YOU ALWAYS THINK THAT IT HAPPENS
TO SOMEONE ELSE.
WE DIDN'T HAVE, REALLY, ANY HOPE
UNTIL WE CAME TO ST. JUDE.
THESE PEOPLE
MEAN BUSINESS.
THESE PEOPLE KNOW
WHATT THEY'RE DOING
GOOD JOB ALEJANDRO.
THEY'RE THE ANSWER TO
OUR PRAYERS.
[ Christy ] AROUND HERE,
KIDS ARE NUMBER ONE.
HAD IT NOT BEEN FOR ST. JUDE,
WE WOULD NOT HAVE HER TODAY.
WE'RE JUST ETERNALLY GRATEFUL
FOR THIS PLACE.
[ Kelly ]
YOU CAN'T GIVE UP,
AND ST. JUDE AND ALL THE DOCTORS
AND NURSES, THEY DON'T GIVE UP.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]  OUR
PHONE LINES WILL REMAIN
OPEN  AFTER  THE
PROGRAM  ENDS.
TO  LERAN  MORE  ABOUT  ST.  J,
GO  TO  WWW.STJUDE.ORG.
♪
ST. JUDE CHILDREN'S
RESEARCH HOSPITAL.
FINDING CURES, SAVING CHILDREN.
THE PRECEDING PROGRAM
WAS SPONSORED BY ST. JUDE
CHILDREN'S RESEARCH HOSPITAL.