>> AGAIN, IT'S PART AND PARCEL
OF WHAT WE DO.
I TOLD INITIALLY WE WILL
LEAVE NO STONE UNTURNED AS WE'RE
LOOKING AT EVERY FACET OF THIS
INVESTIGATION, WHETHER THE
SHOOTER, THE VICTIMS.
WE'RE GOING TO LOOK AT
EVERYTHING.
WE CERTAINLY WILL GO IN AND OUT
OF STATE AND WORK WITH FELLOW
LAW ENFORCEMENT INCLUDING
FEDERAL AGENCIES IF WE NEED TO.
TO ANSWER EVERY SINGLE QUESTION
TO EXACTLY WHAT TRANSPIRED HERE.
AND WE WILL -- IT WILL BE A TIME
CONSUMING PROCESS, BUT WE'LL GET
IT DONE.
RIGHT NOW, ONE SHOOTER.
YES, SIR.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> IT WAS K-4.
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADE.
THAT'S THE SCHOOL.
THEY WERE ALL STUDENTS OF THAT
SCHOOL.
>> ALL IN KINDERGARTEN?
>> I DON'T KNOW THE GRADE THEY
WERE IN.
I'M SORRY.
I DON'T KNOW THAT.
>> ONE CLASS?
>> ONE SECTION, TWO CLASSROOMS.
[ INAUDIBLE ]
>> I COULDN'T TELL YOU.
I DIDN'T FIND THAT OUT.
I'M SORRY?
QUESTION?
>> ANY STUDENTS UNACCOUNTED FOR?
>> NO.
EVERYONE'S BEEN -- AND THAT'S
PART OF -- THAT'S PART OF THE
PROCESS.
THAT'S WHY IT TOOK US SO LONG TO
GET HERE.
THAT'S A VERY GOOD QUESTION.
ARE THERE ANY STUDENTS UP
ACCOUNTED FOR?
WE HAD TO ENSURE WE ACCOUNTED
FOR EVERY SINGLE STUDENT IN THAT
SCHOOL, THAT INCLUDES MAYBE
SOMEONE WHO WAS AN ABSENT FOR
THE DAY WHO DIDN'T COME TO
SCHOOL.
THAT WAS PART OF THE PROCESS WE
HAVE TO GO THROUGH.
NOW WE HAVE THE IDENTIFICATION
PROCESS WHICH IS EVEN MORE
DIFFICULT AND SO IT'S GOING TO
BE SOME TIME BEFORE WE'RE ABLE
TO GIVE YOU THAT INFORMATION.
IT PROBABLY WON'T BE AVAILABLE
UNTIL SOME TIME TOMORROW.
>> THE WEAPONS?
>> DID WE IDENTIFY A WEAPON?
WE HAVE SEIZED THE WEAPONS.
>> WHAT KIND OF WEAPONS?
>> WE WILL NOT DISCUSS THAT AT
THIS TIME.
>> ARE YOU TRYING TO REACH
PARENTS?
>> WE'VE BEEN IN CONTACT WITH
ALL THE PARENTS.
WE WOULD NOT COME UP HERE UNTIL
WE'VE BEEN IN CONTACT WITH ALL
THE PARENTS AND WE'VE BEEN
COMMUNICATING WITH THEM SINCE
THEY ARRIVED HERE AT THE SCENE.
THEY'VE BEEN FULLY INFORMED.
THAT'S, AGAIN, WHY IT TOOK SO
LONG FOR US TO COME UP HERE.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> THAT'S VERY, VERY -- IT'S A
GOOD QUESTION.
EVERYONE BELIEVES THAT, YOU
KNOW, IT'S SOMETHING THAT FIRST
RESPONDERS DO, THAT LAW
ENFORCEMENT DOES, BUT I CAN TELL
YOU, WE'VE PROVIDED COUNSELING
FOR THE FIRST RESPONDERS BECAUSE
THIS WAS A VERY TRAGIC, HORRIFIC
SCENE THAT THEY ENCOUNTERED.
IT'S NOT SOMETHING THAT WE WANT
TO SEE.
IT'S NOT SOMETHING WE SEE EVERY
DAY.
SO THAT WAS ONE -- THAT'S ONE
THING WE HAVE DONE AND THE
COLONEL HAS MADE THAT PERFECTLY
CLEAR THOSE PEOPLE ARE TO BE
SPOKEN TO AND RECEIVE CRISIS
COUNSELING AS REQUIRED.
>> NEWTOWN IS A VERY QUIET,
BEAUTIFUL PLACE.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> THE LIEUTENANT CAN CERTAINLY
TELL YOU, HE'S A NEWTOWN
OFFICER.
SURE.
>> HOW THIS HAS IMPACTED YOU
PERSONALLY, NOT ONLY AS A LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICER, BUT
PERSONALLY.
>> AS A PERSON, THE FIRST THING
I THOUGHT ABOUT WAS MY OWN
CHILDREN.
>> TALK RIGHT IN HERE.
>> LIEUTENANT GEORGE SINKO.
>> WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
S-I-N-K-O.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> YES.
THIS IS MOST DEFINITELY THE
WORST THING WE HAVE EXPERIENCED
HERE IN TOWN.
TRAGIC.
RIGHT NOW, WE'RE CONCERNED ABOUT
THE FAMILIES, THE VICTIMS.
OUR OFFICERS ARE PROFESSIONAL
AND WE WILL DEAL WITH THIS AS
WELL.
>> CAN YOU DESCRIBE THE SCENE
WITH THE PARENTS, PEOPLE GETTING
TOGETHER AND IS A COUNSELOR
THERE FOR THEM?
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
>> THE LOCAL HOSPITAL, DANBURY
HOSPITAL HAS OFFERED THEIR
CRISIS INTERVENTION COUNSELORS.
THEY WILL BE AVAILABLE AT REED
INTERMEDIATE SCHOOL ON WASSERMAN
WAY.
THEY'RE AVAILABLE RIGHT NOW IF
NEED BE AND WILL BE THERE ALL
WEEKEND.
>> IS THERE A PLACE WHERE
PARENTS ARE GATHERING?
CAN YOU DESCRIBE THAT FOR US?
>> THE PARENTS CERTAINLY HAVE
GATHERED AT THE LOCAL FIREHOUSE
WHICH IS ADJACENT TO THE SCHOOL
AND WE'VE DONE OUR BEST TO
COMFORT THEM AND TRY TO REASSURE
THEM THAT WE'VE DONE EVERYTHING
WE CAN.
BUT AS MENTIONED, IT'S A
DIFFICULT PROCESS TO CONFIRM THE
STATUS OF AN ENTIRE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AND WE NEED TO BE RIGHT
WHEN WE DO THAT.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> YEAH, WE'LL BE WORKING.
>> FEELING.
WE JUST HAVE TO THINK ABOUT THE
FAMILIES RIGHT NOW AND DO
EVERYTHING WE CAN FOR THEM.
>> LIEUTENANT, WAS ONE OF THE
TEACHERS KILLED THE SHOOTER'S
MOM?
>> WE CAN'T CONFIRM ANY OF THAT
RIGHT NOW.
THE INVESTIGATION IS ONGOING.
>> ARE PARENTS AT THE FIREHOUSE?
>> THERE ARE STILL PARENTS
THERE, YES.
I DON'T HAVE A NUMBER FOR YOU.
>> WHEN DID YOU REALIZE -- HOW
LONG DID IT TAKE YOU TO REALIZE
THE MAGNITUDE?
>> MINUTES AFTER OUR OFFICERS
WERE THERE, THEY REALIZED, YOU
KNOW, WHAT A HORRIFIC SCENE WE
HAD THERE.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> I DON'T HAVE THE EXACT
TIMELINE ON THAT.
CERTAINLY OFFICERS RESPONDED
IMMEDIATELY AND AS SOON AS THEY
REALIZED WHAT THEY HAD, WE
OBVIOUSLY ASKED FOR ALL THE
RESOURCES WE COULD GET.
ALL RIGHT?
THANK YOU.
>> I THINK WE'RE GOOD THANK YOU.
>> THAT IS THE TEAM THERE IN
CONNECTICUT, LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE OF THE CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE.
THEY'RE GOING TO BRIEF AGAIN IN
ANOTHER HOUR FROM NOW, AS IS
OFTEN THE CASE AFTER THESE
TRAGEDIES.
THEY NOW HAVE THE TOUGH TASK OF
COMING BEFORE THE CAMERA EVERY
SO OFTEN.
WHAT WE LEARNED IN THAT BRIEFING
JUST MOMENTS AGO WAS THAT ALL OF
THE PARENTS HAVE NOW BEEN
CONTACTED.
ALL HAVE BEEN INFORMED.
20 CHILDREN DIED TODAY.
18 INSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
INCLUDING THE KINDERGARTEN
TEACHER AND MANY OF THE CHILDREN
IN HER CLASSROOM.
THERE WERE SIX ADULTS AND
THERE'S ANOTHER ADULT AT A
SEPARATE LOCATION IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AND WE'LL HAVE MUCH
MORE ON THAT AS THE EVENING
PROGRESSES.
WE'LL HAVE CONTINUING COVERAGE
ON THIS, A SPECIAL ONE OUR
EDITION OF "WORLD NEWS" WITH
DIANE SAWYER.
DIANE IS ON THE SCENE WHERE
SHE'S BEEN REPORTING ALL
AFTERNOON.
A SPECIAL "2020" FOLLOWED BY
"NIGHTLINE" TONIGHT AND "GOOD
MORNING AMERICA" FIRST THING IN
THE MORNING.
I THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US
ALL AFTERNOON.
AS WE LEAVE YOU WITH THE IMAGES
OF THIS VERY TRYING AFTERNOON IN
AMERICA, WE MUST REMEMBER THERE
ARE 20 SETS OF PARENTS OUT THERE
WHOSE LITTLE CHILDREN DID NOT
COME HOME TODAY.
WE'LL SEE YOU SHORTLY ON "WORLD
NEWS."
[CAPTIONING MADE
[cheers and applause]
>> HELLO, EVERYBODY,
AND WELCOME TO MILLIONAIRE.
WELL, IT IS THE FINAL DAY
OF BROADWAY GIVEAWAY WEEK,
AND OUR RETURNING CONTESTANT
IS PLAYING FOR BIG MONEY
AND ALSO FOR TICKETS
TO MARY POPPINS FOR HERSELF
AND AN ENTIRE ROW
OF OUR AUDIENCE TODAY.
[cheers and applause]
FROM JERSEY CITY, NEW JERSEY,
PLEASE WELCOME
SHERRY-ANN ROWLAND.
[cheers and applause]
HI, BABY DOLL.
MWAH!
OH, SHERRY-ANN,
I HEARD YOU BACKSTAGE
A FEW MINUTES AGO
SAYING THAT YOU WERE HAVING
SORT OF A CINDERELLA
MOMENT HERE.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
>> MEREDITH, YOU KNOW,
I'M LOOKING AT MY BANK
BACKSTAGE, AND--
>> $13,500, BY THE WAY.
>> LET ME TELL YOU,
IT'S MY FAIRY TALE.
IT'S ABSOLUTELY MY FAIRY TALE.
I'M LIVING MY DREAM.
I CAN'T EVEN BELIEVE
I'M HERE WITH YOU.
IT'S SO EXCITING.
I JUST CELEBRATED 15 YEARS
OF WEDDING ANNIVERSARY
WITH MY HUSBAND.
>> OH, CONGRATULATIONS.
OH.
>> MY PRINCE CHARMING.
>> AW.
>> BUT I'M HERE TO WIN
BIG MONEY TO CONTINUE
THAT FAIRY TALE, I GOT TO SAY.
>> WELL, YOU'RE ON THE WAY,
FOR SURE.
AS WE JUST SAID,
$13,500 IN YOUR BANK,
10 AWAY FROM THE MILLION.
YOU HAVE TWO LIFELINES
REMAINING, AND YOU'VE STILL GOT
THAT BROADWAY QUESTION.
YOU GET THAT RIGHT
AND YOU GET TICKETS
TO MARY POPPINS
AND SOME MEMBERS OF OUR AUDIENCE
WILL
>> WONDERFUL.
>> SO ARE YOU READY?
>> I AM READY.
>> AUDIENCE, ARE YOU READY?
[cheers and applause]
THEN LET'S PLAY MILLIONAIRE.
HERE YOU GO, SHERRY-ANN.
NOT REFERENCING EATING HABITS,
PSYCHOLOGY TODAY CALLS WHO
"THE SANDWICH GENERATION"
BECAUSE OF PRESSURES FACED
BY THEIR ADULT CHILDREN
AND AILING PARENTS?
>> YOU KNOW, THE MILLENNIALS,
YOU KNOW, I WANT TO SAY
THAT'S MY GENERATION, MAYBE.
I DON'T KNOW IF I'M TELLING
MY AGE, BUT I WANT TO SAY
THAT'S MY GENERATION.
GOOD WARRIORS--
I'M NOT FAMILIAR WITH.
HARD TIMERS...
MAYBE BABY BOOMERS--
JUST SOUNDS LIKE, YOU KNOW--
MY MOM'S A BABY BOOMER,
AND, YOU KNOW,
YOU KNOW?
AND SHE HAS ADULT CHILDREN,
OBVIOUSLY.
YOU KNOW, EVEN THOUGH
I DON'T WANT TO ADMIT IT.
BUT, YOU KNOW...
IT JUST MAKES SENSE.
I'M GONNA GO WITH--SAY, "B,"
BABY BOOMERS, FINAL ANSWER.
>> I'M A BABY BOOMER.
YOU GOT IT RIGHT.
IT WAS BABY BOOMERS.
ALL
LET'S PUT MORE MONEY
IN THAT BANK.
YOU WANT IT.
YOU'RE GETTING IT.
$1,000.
$14,500.
5 QUESTIONS LEFT IN ROUND 1.
THE BIG, BIG MONEY
IS STILL UP THERE.
ALL THE MONEY LOOKS GOOD,
THOUGH.
"CAREER CHANGE."
EARNING AN IMPRESSIVE
72 DELEGATE VOTES,
WHAT SITCOM ICON CAME IN SECOND
IN THE RACE FOR
THE 2012 GREEN PARTY
PRESIDENTIAL NOMINATION?
>> HMM.
CANDICE BERGEN...
I'M NOT EVEN SURE
WHAT SHE'S BEEN DOING LATELY.
UM...
ROSEANNE BARR...
DOESN'T SEEM LIKE, YOU KNOW,
THAT SHE WOULD BE
RUNNING FOR PRESIDENT.
I HOPE NOT.
[laughter]
UM, YOU KNOW,
I'M KIND OF TORN BETWEEN
MICHAEL J. FOX--
HE JUST SEEMS LIKE HE'S,
YOU KNOW, IN THE MIX OF THINGS,
YOU KNOW, WITH THINGS GOING ON
IN CONGRESS AND SENATE,
YOU KNOW.
SMART GUY, YOU KNOW.
BILL COSBY...
YOU KNOW, BILL IS ALWAYS
IN THE NEWS, BUT...
I DON'T THINK FOR ANYTHING
DEALING WITH THE
PRESIDENTIAL NOMINATION,
THAT I'VE HEARD OF, YOU KNOW?
I LIKE MY NEWS.
I TRY TO KEEP UPDATED.
72 DELEGATES.
SITCOM ICON.
YOU KNOW WHAT, MEREDITH?
I THINK I'M GONNA HAVE
TO JUMP THE QUESTION.
I'M JUST NOT 100% CONFIDENT.
>> THAT'S A SMART MOVE.
QUESTION'S OUT OF PLAY.
LET'S SEE THE ANSWER.
WAS IT MICHAEL J. FOX?
IT WAS...
IT WAS THE WOMAN
YOU DIDN'T EXPECT TO BE
GETTING THAT...
>> SHAME ON ME.
>> NOMINATION, ROSEANNE BARR.
OKAY, LET'S SEE
WHAT YOU JUMPED OVER,
SHERRY-ANN.
GOOD MOVE.
$2,000.
NOT BAD.
LOWEST AMOUNT YOU STILL HAD
REMAINING UP THERE.
SO THAT'S NOT BAD.
AND BY TAKING THAT JUMP,
YOU'RE NOW 8 AWAY
FROM $1 MILLION.
"WEATHER ON THE RADIO"
IS THE CATEGORY.
CONSIDERING THE LOCAL CLIMATE,
RESIDENTS OF NOME, ALASKA,
CAN TUNE THEIR RADIOS TO 850 AM
AND LISTEN TO A STATION
WITH WHAT APT NAME?
>> OOH.
I KNOW VERY LITTLE ABOUT ALASKA.
LOCAL CLIMATE...
OH.
[audience laughs]AY.AY.
[applause]
I'M GONNA GO "C," FINAL ANSWER..
K-ICY.
[laughs]
ALL RIGHT, SHERRY-ANN,
LET'S SEE THE MONEY.
WHAT ARE WE TALKING ABOUT?
$7,000.
>> NICE!
>> FOR $21,500.
>> VERY NICE.
>> 3 QUESTIONS LEFT
IN ROUND 1.
GOOD MONEY UP THERE.
"DISEASE CONTROL."
IN 1947, 6 MILLION NEW YORKERS
RY
NS, SUCCESSFULLY
THWARTING AN OUTBREAK
OF WHAT DISEASE?
>> OKAY.
OKAY.
I THINK I KNOW THE ANSWER.
LIKE, I HAVE A GUT FEELING
OF WHAT I THINK IT IS.
HOWEVER, I'M GOING TO HAVE
TO ASK THE AUDIENCE ON THIS.
THEY LOOK LIKE SMART PEOPLE,
MEREDITH.
>> OKAY, AUDIENCE,
SHERRY-ANN NEEDS YOUR HELP.
ON YOUR KEYPADS, VOTE NOW.
[percussive music]
♪
62% BELIEVE IT IS POLIO.
WHAT WERE YOU THINKING?
>> I WAS THINKING POLIO.
I WAS THINKING POLIO.
I JUST THINK CHOLERA
AND THE BUBONIC PLAGUE
SEEMS A LITTLE BIT FURTHER--
YOU KNOW, EARLIER ON THAN 1947.
UM...
I'M GONNA GO WITH THE AUDIENCE.
"A," POLIO, FINAL ANSWER.
>> THAT CAME LATER.
IT WAS SMALLPOX...
>> OH.
>> WAS THE ANSWER.
I AM SO SORRY, SHERRY-ANN.
>> OH, MAN.
>> BUT YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU WERE FANTASTIC.
I WOULD'VE DONE THE SAME THING.
THAT NUMBER WAS A HIGH ONE.
>> THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU, SWEETHEART.
PLEASURE TO HAVE YOU HERE.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK, GUYS,
WITH MORE MILLIONAIRE
RIGHT AFTER THIS.
Whatever it takes,
get to Sears Super Saturday,
with Friday preview.
Coats are 19.99,
and save even more with pass.
Get ½ Carat Diamond
earrings for $49.99.
Plus, all Craftsman wrench
sets are on sale.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
PREGO?!
BUT I'VE BOUGHT RAGU FOR YEARS.
[ Thinking ] WONDER WHAT OTHER
QUESTIONABLE CHOICES I'VE MADE?
I CHOOSE DATE NUMBER 2!
WHOOO!
[ sigh of relief ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHOOSE TASTE. CHOOSE PREGO.
>> AND WELCOME BACK
TO MILLIONAIRE
BROADWAY GIVEAWAY WEEK.
DANA GOLD FROM FOREST HILLS,
NEW YORK,
IS OUR NEXT CONTESTANT.
YOU ARE AN ATTORNEY--
A SMART LADY, OBVIOUSLY.
>> HOPEFULLY.
>> LAST NAME "GOLD,"
SO THAT FITS IN WITH THE WHOLE
THEME HERE OF MAKING
A LOT OF MONEY.
>> LET'S HOPE SO.
>> SO LET'S TAKE A LOOK
AT THE MONEY IN YOUR ROUND 1.
COMPUTER, PLEASE RANDOMIZE
THE DOLLAR AMOUNTS
AND THE CATEGORIES
TO THE QUESTIONS.
AND NOW LET'S SEE
WHERE YOUR BROADWAY QUESTION IS.
THERE IT IS.AND YOU WILL BE PL
AND YOU WILL BE PLAYING,
ACTUALLY, FOR TICKETS
TO DISNEY'S HIT MUSICAL
TONY AWARD-WINNING NEWSIES.
YOU'LL WIN IT AND SO WILL
A ROW OF OUR AUDIENCE
IF YOU GET THE ANSWER
TO THE QUESTION RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, NOW THAT EVERYTHING
IS ALL SHUFFLED,
ARE YOU READY?
>> SUPER READY.
THEN LET'S PLAY MILLIONAIRE.
[dramatic musical flourish]
ALL RIGHT, DANA, HERE YOU GO.
FITTINGLY, WHICH OF THESE
CANDY BRANDS SELLS ITS OWN BRAND
OF PEA
>> I LIKE PEANUT BUTTER A LOT,
SO I KNOW IT IS "C," REESE'S,
FINAL ANSWER.
>> I LOVE REESE'S.
YOU OBVIOUSLY GOT IT RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, DANA,
GOOD JOB ON THE FIRST QUESTION.
LET'S START BUILDING YOUR BANK.
$5,000.
THAT'S VERY NICE.
$5,000 IN THE BANK,
13 QUESTIONS TO GO.
"WHAT AN HONOR."
RELEASED IN "NORMAL"
AND "SILKSCREEN" VERSIONS,
A COLLECTIBLE DOLL
MADE IN WHAT ARTIST'S LIKENESS
FEATURES INTERCHANGEABLE HAIR
NA?NA?
>> BANANA MIGHT BE A KEY HERE.
JACKSON POLLOCK, I KNOW,
DOES CRAZY, SPLOTCHY PAINTINGS.
ANDY WARHOL, I KNOW,
HAS DONE THE CAMPBELL SOUP.
DALI...
WHAT ARTIST'S LIKENESS.
YOU KNOW, MEREDITH,
I'M NOT--NOTHING IS--
I'M NOT 100% SURE.
I'M GONNA JUMP THIS ONE.
>> OKAY, QUESTION'S OUT OF PLAY.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO ANSWER IT.
LET'S SEE THE ANSWER.
ANDY WARHOL
WAS THE CORRECT ANSWER.
LET'S SEE WHAT YOU JUMPED OVER.
HOPEFULLY NOT TOO MUCH MONEY.
>> OH!
IT'S OKAY.
>> THAT'S OKAY.
YOU DIDN'T KNOW THE ANSWER,
SO YOU HAD TO MAKE THAT JUMP.
IT'S KEPT YOU IN THE GAME.
NOW 12 QUESTIONS AWAY
FROM THE MILLION.
"DOUBLE B."
ACTRESS BLAIR BROWN
HAS THE DISTINCTION OF HAVING
A FIRST AND LAST NAME
THAT WERE THE LAST NAMES
OF CONSECUTIVE WHAT?
>> SO I KNOW TONY BLAIR
WAS A PRIME MINISTER.
I HAVE TO CONFESS,
I REALLY DON'T KNOW MUCH
ABOUT SUPER BOWL MVPs.
AMERICAN IDOL WINNERS...
I CAN'T THINK OF ANY
BLAIRS OR BROWNS.
NOBEL PRIZE WINNERS...
UM...
I'M GONNA GO WITH
U.K. PRIME MINISTERS, "C,"
FINAL.
>> YOU GOT IT RIGHT.
THAT'S ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
TONY BLAIR AND GORDON BROWN
WERE THE TWO.
LET'S GET SOME MORE MONEY
IN THAT BANK OF YOURS, DANA.
$500.
OKAY, $5,500.
NOW 11 AWAY FROM THE MILLION.
"NOBODY'S FOOL"
IS YOUR CATEGORY.
CAPITALIZING ON HIS FAMOUS
CATCH PHRASE, WHO ONCE RELEASED
A MOTIVATIONAL VIDEO TITLED
BE SOMEBODY...
OR BE SOMEBODY'S FOOL?
>> SO IN TERMS OF CATCH PHRASES,
I KNOW DONALD TRUMP IS,
"YOU'RE FIRED."
EMERIL IS, "KICK IT UP A NOTCH."
ED MCMAHON,
A LITTLE BEFORE MY TIME.
UH...
>> THAT HURTS WHEN YOU SAY THAT.
>> I'M SORRY.
I'M SORRY.
>> IT REALLY HURTS.
IT'S OKAY. IT'S OKAY.
>> IT SOUNDS LIKE SOMETHING
MR. T WOULD SAY.
"C," MR. T, FINAL ANSWER.
>> YEAH, YOU GOT IT.
MR. T.
ALL RIGHT, DANA,
LET'S SEE THE MONEY.
$7,000.
UP TO $12,500.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE A LITTLE BREAK.
WE'LL BE BACK WITH MORE
MILLIONAIRE RIGHT AFTER THIS.
THAT LOOKS GREAT.
>> IT DOES.
IT REALLY DOES.
ñ
>> WELCOME BACK TO MILLIONAIRE'S
BROADWAY GIVEAWAY WEEK,
WHERE DANA GOLD
FROM FOREST HILLS, NEW YORK,
IS GOING FOR
THE MILLION DOLLARS.
YOUR FOLKS, VICKY AND MARK,
ARE IN THE AUDIENCE.
A BIG HELLO TO BOTH OF YOU GUYS
AS WELL.
$12,500 IN YOUR BANK,
DANA, SO FAR,
10 AWAY FROM THE MILLION.
YOU STILL GOT 2 LIFELINES.
DOING A GREAT JOB.
YOU READY TO KEEP PLAYING?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> THEN LET'S PLAY.
[dramatic musical flourish]
BEFORE BECOMING
A WILDLY SUCCESSFUL AUTHOR,
J.K. ROWLING WORKED
AS A RESEARCHER
FOR WHAT NONPROFIT ORGANIZATION?
>> I WISH THIS WAS A QUESTION
ABOUT HARRY POTTER
BECAUSE I WOULD KNOW IT.
UM...
YOU KNOW, MEREDITH,
I'M GONNA HAVE TO JUMP THIS ONE.
I REALLY DON'T KNOW.
>> NO PROBLEM.
QUESTION'S OUT OF PLAY.
LET'S SEE THE CORRECT ANSWER.
AMNESTY INTERNATIONAL
WAS THE RIGHT ANSWER.
LAST TIME, YOU JUMPED OVER
$25,000.
IT CAN'T BE THAT BAD THIS TIME.
SO LET'S SEE
WHAT YOU JUMPED OVER.
>> OH!
>> ALL RIGHT, WELL...
>> IT'S OKAY.
>> YEAH, WHO NEEDS THAT ANYHOW,
RIGHT?
>> YEAH.
>> THE JUMP KEEPS YOU
IN THE GAME.
9 AWAY FROM THE MILLION NOW.
"SHOW SOME SPIRIT."
HELD EVERY YEAR
AT UNIVERSAL ORLANDO RESORT,
THE U.S. SPIRIT
NATIONAL CHAMPIONSHIPS
IS A COMPETITION FOR WHICH
OF THESE GROUPS
OF HIGH SCHOOL STUDENTS?
>> UM, I'M FAMILIAR
WITH THE SPIRIT STICK.
I WOULD...
I WOULD THINK THAT WOULD MEAN
"D," CHEERLEADERS, FINAL.
>> IT DOES MEAN THAT.
YOU WERE RIGHT, DANA.
LET'S PUT SOME MONEY
IN YOUR BANK.
$2,000.
UP TO $14,500.
4 QUESTIONS LEFT IN ROUND 1.
"EYES HAVE IT"
IS THE NEXT CATEGORY.
WHILE THE MYTHOLOGICAL CYCLOPS
WAS A GIANT ONE-EYED MONSTER,
THE ANIMAL SCIENTIFICALLY
CLASSIFIED AS CYCLOPS
IS A TYPE OF TINY WHAT?
>> SO IF THIS MEANS "CYCLOPS"
AS HAVING ONE EYE...
SNAKES HAVE TWO EYES.
SPIDERS, I BELIEVE,
HAVE TWO EYES.
SCIENTIFICALLY CLASSIFIED
AS A TINY TYPE
TYPE OF TINY WHAT?
I DON'T KNOW IF WORMS
HAVE ANY EYES.
CRUSTACEAN IS A GROUP OF THING.
IT COULD BE...
HOW MUCH IS IN M
RIGHT NOW?
>> $14,500,
AND YOU HAVE A LIFELINE.
YOU CAN STILL ASK THE AUDIENCE.
>> WELL, I'LL POLL THE AUDIENCE.
I'LL SEE WHAT THEY SAY.
>> NO PROBLEM.
AUDIENCE, DANA NEEDS YOUR HELP.
ON YOUR KEYPADS, VOTE NOW.
[percussive music]
♪
54% SAY CRUSTACEAN,
30% SAY WORM,
AND DOWN FROM THERE.
>> HMM.
54% IS MORE THAN HALF.
UM...
I'LL GO WITH "C," CRUSTACEAN,
FINAL.
>> YOU GOT IT.
IT IS CRUSTACEAN.
I HOPE THERE'S $10,000
BEHIND THIS QUESTION.
THAT WOULD BE NICE.
LET'S CHECK IT OUT.
YOU GOT THE $10,000!
$24,500.
DANA, YOU KEEP BOUNCING
ALL YOU WANT.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK
WITH MORE MILLIONAIRE
RIGHT AFTER THIS.
>> HERE IS YOUR
QUESTION OF THE DAY:
STAY TUNED FOR THE ANSWER.