THERE ARE MANY TROPICAL
DESTINATIONS WHERE BLUE
WATERS, WHITE SAND AND
PERFECT WEATHER CREATE
LOCATIONS MANY CONSIDER
HEAVEN ON EARTH.
AND THIS PLACE IS CLOSE
TO THE TOP OF THAT LIST.
THE BRITISH
VIRGIN ISLANDS.
MADE UP OF NEARLY 60 SMALL
ISLANDS EAST OF PUERTO RICO
THE BRITISH VIRGIN
ISLANDS, REGULARLY CALLED THE
BVIS ARE LARGELY UNINHABITED AND
BEST EXPLORED BY BOAT.
WE TEAMED UP WITH ONE OF
THE TOP SAIL BOAT CHARTER
COMPANIES IN THE BVIS,
CONCH CHARTERS TO EXPERIENCE THE
MAGIC OF THIS ISLAND PARADISE
BY SAILING ITS CALM SEAS.
THE BRITISH VIRGIN ISLANDS
ARE POPULAR TO SAIL,
CONSIDERED VERY EASY TO
NAVIGATE, WITH FAVORABLE
WINDS, EASY FOR EVEN
INEXPERIENCED SAILORS.
SINCE OUR MOTION CAMERAMAN
JOHN NEILY HAPPENS
TO BE A VERY EXPERIENCED
SAILOR WE PLANNED A BARE
BOAT CHARTER HERE, MEANING
WE CREWED OUR OWN BOAT TO
EXPLORE SEVERAL OF THE
ISLANDS AND DISCOVER THE
BEAUTY FOUND ABOVE AND
BELOW THE SURFACE OF THE
BRITISH VIRGIN ISLANDS.
CONCH CHARTERS HOOKED US UP WITH
A BEAUTIFUL 43 FOOT CATAMARAN
CALLED THE CATY WAMPUS.
WITH PLENTY OF ROOM INSIDE
AND OUT FOR THE MOTION
CREW AND TWO GUEST HIKERS.
GINA AND KATIE ARE BEST
FRIENDS WHO HAVEN'T SEEN
EACH OTHER IN OVER TWO
YEARS AND RECONNECTED FOR
A TRIP WITH US TO THE
BRITISH VIRGIN ISLANDS.
EXCITED AND A LITOAT I WAS
EXCITED AND A LITTLE NERVOUS TO
SPEND THREE DAYS ON A BOAT WITH
PEOPLE IVE NEVER MET, BUT ONCE I
MET GREG AND THE CREW EVERYTHING
WAS FINE, WE WERE ALL FRIEND.
I'VE NEVER BEEN ON A BIG
SAIL BOAT BEFORE I THOUGHT
I HOPE SOMEONE KNOWS WHAT
THEY'RE DOING
BECAUSE I DON'T.
THEN WE MET THE CREW AND
WERE REALLY EXCITED.
AFTER GETTING OUR GEAR
STOWED BELOW DECK WE EASED
THE CATY WAMPUS OUT OF
THE HARBOR AND POINTED HER
TOWARD THE FIRST
DESTINATION AN OUTCROPPING
OR ROCKS WITH SOME GREAT
SNORKELING IN THE BVI'S
CALLED THE INDIANS.
AFTER USING THE TWIN
DIESEL ENGINES TO SAFELY
MOTOR OUT OF PORT PUTTING
THE CARIBBEAN
BREEZE INTO MOTION.
JOHN WASTED LITTLE TIME
BEFORE PUTTING THE GUEST
HIKERS AND I TO WORK.
GINA, AND I AND KATIE
WERE JUST SITTING THERE
WATCHING THE WAVES GO BY
BUT NOW WE HAVE TO
GO HOIST SOMETHING.
ONE HAND ON THE
ZIPPER ONE ON THE.
I'M JUST GOING TO WATCH.
CAN I TAKE THAT MIDDLE
MANAGEMENT POSITION?
UP INTO THE WIND AND
THEN HOIST HER UP.
OKAY?
GET ALL THAT?
GOT IT?
OKAY.
JUST TELL ME WHAT TO PULL.
EVERYONE ON BOARD HELPED SAIL
THE CATY WAMPUS WHICH MADE A TRP
LIKE THIS SO FUN.
BEFORE HOISTING THE SAIL
HE HOISTED IT INTO THE
WIND SO IT WOULD BE EASIER
HOISTING THE
ENORMOUS MAIN SHEET.
GIVE THAT A GOOD SOLID
CRANK, LIKE YOU MEAN IT.
SORRY I HAVE TO SQUINT A
LITTLE BIT RIGHT NOW CAUSE I
CAUGHT A GLARE OFF KATIE'S TOES.
ONE IS FASTER
THAN THE OTHER.
YOU'VE GOT THIS BRO.
GO KATIE GO.
SEE THIS IS TOUGH
WORK SAILING.
YOU DON'T GET TO
JUST SAIL, HAVE TO
CRANK AND HOIST.
YEA SERIOUSLY.
WHEN THEY ASKED ME TO DO
SOMETHING, I THOUGHT OH
NO, I DON'T KNOW WHO THEY
ASKED, BUT IT WAS A
CHALLENGE BUT FUN, AND
HIGH ENERGY AND EVERYONE
WAS HELPFUL AND IT
WAS NEAT TO BE PART
OF THE SAILING.
THE MAIN SAIL OUT AND THE
SMALLER TRIANGLE SHAPE JIB
DEPLOYED THE LOW RUMBLE OF
THE ENGINE QUITE AND THE
PEACE OF SAILING SET IN.
PART OF WHAT MAKING
THE BVIS EASY TO SAIL
IS NAVIGATION IS EASY.
YOU CAN SEE MOST OF THE
ISLANDS AT ALL TIMES.
THE INDIANS A NEAR BY
NORMAN ISLAND ARE A SHORT
DISTANCE FROM THIS TOWN.
WITH THE CATY WAMPUS
SAILING AT SIX KNOTS IT
TOOK A LITTLE MORE THAN AN
HOUR, WHERE WE TIED UP
LAUNCHED OUR SMALL DINGY AND
GOT INTO AN UNDERWATER REEF.
ONE OF THE FIRST THINGS THAT
STRUCK ME ABOUT THE BVIS WAS
HOW CLEAR THE WATER WAS.
WE CAN SEE THE BOTTOM OF
THE OCEAN AND 70 FEET OF
WATER AND ONCE WE GOT IN
HERE IN ONLY 15 FEET OF
WATER THE COLORS BELOW THE
SURFACE WAS EYE POPPING.
IT WAS TRULY BEAUTIFUL.
I HAD NEVER SNORKELED
IN A REEF LIKE THAT.
TO SEE THE CLIFFS AND
STUFF IT WAS AMAZING.
THE MIXED UNDERWATER
TOPOGRAPHY HERE IS WHAT
MAKES THE INDIANS ONE OF
THE TOP PLACES TO
SNORKEL IN ALL OF THE
BRITISH VIRGIN ISLANDS.
ON ONE SIDE OF THE ROCKS
THE SHALLOW REEF IS HOME
TO TROPICAL FISH, LARGE
CORAL AND A STAGGERING
AMOUNT OF UNDERSEA LIFE.
WHEN YOU FIRST EXPERIENCE
A PLACE LIKE THIS IT IS
EASY TO BE OVERWHELMED BY
THE LARGE SCALE
OF EVERYTHING.
BUT IF YOU JUST STOP AND
FOCUS ON ONE PIECE OF
CORAL AND HANG OUT THERE
FOR A FEW MINUTES YOU
START TO SEE THINGS MOST
PEOPLE MISS AS THEY TRY TO
QUICKLY COVER
THE ENTIRE AREA.
ON THE SOUTH SIDE OF THE
INDIANS THE SEA FLOOR
DROPS AWAY OVER 700 FEET
IN DEPTH GIVING A
WHOLE NEW ADVENTURE.
CRUISING ALONG THIS ROCK
WALL REVEALED NEW KINDS OF
CORAL AND FISH THAT MADE
THIS ONE OF THE BEST
SNORKELS WE'VE EVER DONE.
AFTER AN HOUR IN THE AFTER
WE HEADED BACK TO THE
CATY WAMPUS FOR A QUICK
RIDE INTO A COVE
CALLED THE BIGHT.
FIELDS ARE SPREAD OUT ON
THE ISLAND ON PROTECTED
SHORES AND ARE WHERE
PEOPLE TIE UP AND
CAMP FOR THE NIGHT.
WITH PLENTY OF DAYLIGHT
REMAINING WE GOT READY FOR
ANOTHER SNORKEL OUTING ON
SEA CAVES BY THE POINT.
THIS HARBOR IS CALLED THE
BIGHT ON NORMAN ISLAND IN
THE BRITISH VIRGIN ISLANDS.
HOW IS IT GOING GIRLS?
GOOD.
WHAT DO YOU FEEL
ABOUT GOING INTO A
BIG CAVE RIGHT NOW?
EXCITED, VERY EXCITED
OKAY AND BARRACUDAS
DON'T BOTHER YOU.
AND SHARKS DON'T
BOTHER YOU?
OKAY MAYBE THOSE.
OKAY CAUSE WERE ALL
NERVOUS ABOUT THE SHARKS
WERE GOING TO ENCOUNTER.
DID YOU HEAR THAT LOUD
EXPLOSION OVER THERE?
THAT WAS SIGNALING
HAPPY HOUR.
A SHORT RIDE IN THE DINGY LEAD
US HERE A CLIFF WALL IN THE SOUH
SHORES OF NORMAN ISLAND.
BARRACUDAS ARE COMMON IN
THESE WATERS AS ARE SMALL
REEF SHARKS, BOTH OF WHICH
WE WERE LOOKING
FORWARD TO SEE.
WHILE THE SHARKS WERE ON THE
SHY SIDE FOR THE SNORKEL WE
DID SEE INCREDIBLE MARINE LIFE
INSIDE AND OUT OF THE CAVES,
MAKING THIS ANOTHER AMAZING SWI.
BACK ON THE DECK OF THE
CATY WAMPUS WE SETTLED
IN FOR THE NIGHT AND
DISCOVERED FIRST HAND WHY
SUNSETS OVER THE BRITISH
VIRGIN ISLANDS ARE SO FAMOUS.
OUR FIRST NIGHT ON THE
BOAT GINA AND I WERE
HAVING A GLASS OF WINE AND
THE SUN WAS SETTING BEHIND
US AND WE WERE CHATTING
AWAY AND WE TURNED AROUND
AND WE WERE SPEECHLESS, AND ITS
WAS EPIC AND SOMETHING YOU
COULDN'T SEE ANYWHERE ELSE.
UP NEXT, IT'S A FIRST FOR
OUR GUEST HIKERS AND ME,
AS WE LEARN TO SCUBA DIVE
ON COOPER ISLAND, THEN WE
TAKE OUR DIVE DEEP AND
EXPLORE THE WRECK OF A
MASSIVE BRITISH SHIP
WHEN MOTION RETURNS.
WERE EXPLORING
THE BRITISH VIRGIN ISLANDS
BY SAIL BOAT WITH TWO LONG
LOST FRIENDS REUNITED
AS GUEST HIKERS
ON THIS AMAZING TRIP.
WE TEAMED UP WITH CONCH
CHARTERS ONE OF THE TOP
SAILBOAT CHARTER COMPANIES
IN THE BVIS AND SET SAIL
ON THE CATY WAMPUS, THIS
43 FOOT VESSEL IS THE
PERFECT WAY TO EXPLORE
THIS AREA WITH MOTION
GUIDE JOHN, BROTHER JEFF,
AND DAVE HANDLING THE
CAPTAIN AND CREW DUTIES.
AFTER SNORKELING THE NORMAN
ISLANDS AND MORING
OVERNIGHT AT A COVE CALLED
THE BIGHT, WE MADE THE
SHORT RUN TOWARD COOPER
ISLAND TO THE EAST TO DO
SOMETHING I'VE ALWAYS
WANTED TO TRY.
SCUBA DIVING.
ALRIGHT WELL ANOTHER BEAUTIFUL
MORNING UP HERE ON THE BOW OF TE
CATY WAMPUS, AND YOU CAN
SEE WERE HEADING TO COOPER
ISLAND WHERE WERE GOING TO MEET
UP WITH OUR DIVE CREW.
SUPER EXCITED.
NEVER SCUBA BEFORE AND WERE
GOING TO DIVE THE WRECK OF THE
ROAN, A 300 FOOT VESSAL AND ONE
OF A KIND FROM THE ROYAL NAVY
BUILT IN 1865, BEING ONE OF THE
FIRST TO USE BOTH STEAM ENGINES
AND SAILS IT WAS DEEMED
UNSINKABLE AND WAS POPULAR WITH
THE CREW AND PASSENGERS.
BUT IN 1867 THE ROAN WAS
CAUGHT IN A VIOLENT
HURRICANE AND SANK OFF THE
ISLAND WITH 150 PEOPLE ON
BOARD ONLY 23 SURVIVED.
ON COOPER ISLAND WE TEAMED
UP WITH ANOTHER BVI
OUTFITTER TO TEACH US TO
DIVE AND EXPLORE THE
WRECK OF THE ROAN.
SAIL CARIBBEAN DIVERS.
THE DIVE MASTER KELSEY
GREETED US AT THE DOCK AND
GAVE US THE BASICS RIGHT AWAY.
I KNEW WE WERE GOING
DIVING AND THOUGHT A LOT
ABOUT IT, BUT RIGHT BEFORE
WE GOT THERE AND WE SIGNED
THE PAPERWORK AND THEN IT
HITS YOU A BIT AND THEN
YOU'RE OKAY I'VE NEVER
DONE ANYTHING LIKE THIS
BEFORE, THEN ALL THE SUDDEN
WITH THE EMERGENCY PROCEDURES
ITS NERVE WRACKING BUT THE MINUE
WE GOT INTO THE WATER
IT WAS AN AWESOME EXPERIENCE
AND ADRENALINE KICKS IN MORE
THAN ANYTHING ELSE.
AFTER THE BASICS ON THE BEACH IT
WAS TIME TO GEAR UP FOR OUR FIRT
BREATHE IN THE WATER.
A TYPICAL RESORT COURSE
LIKE THIS LIMITS IT 40
FEET, BUT BEFORE WE GO
DOWN THAT DEEP WE NEED TO
LEARN HOW TO BREATH IN THE
WAIST DEEP WATER BY THE DOCK.
YOU GO, WE GO, A TEAM.
KNOWING HOW TO SAFELY DEAL WITH
POTENTIAL HAZARDS IS WHAT THIS
PART OF THE TRIP WAS ALL ABOUT.
KELSEY AND THE TEAM
REALLY KNOW THEIR STUFF
AND TOOK CARE OF US.
AFTER GETTING SOME BASIC
SAFETY TRAINING DOWN WE
LEARNED A LITTLE DEEPER
AND USED OUR GEAR
TO KEEP US BUOYANT
A DIFFERENT DEPTHS.
EVERYONE CHECKED OUT WE GOT OUT
OF THE WATER AND ON THE DIVE BOT
TO THE WRECK OF THE ROAN.
ONCE WE TIED UP DIRECTLY
OVER THE WRECK IT WENT OVER
WHAT WE WOULD BE SEEING BELOW.
WHEN THE ROAN WENT DOWN
SHE BROKE IN HALF WITH THE
BOW IN 80 FEET OF WATER,
THE STERN IS IN JUST 40
FEET OF WATER, WHICH IS
WHERE WE ARE HEADED NEXT.
YAH, WHEN I GOT UNDER THE
WATER THE FIRST TIME WE
WERE SCUBA DIVING I SAW
THE SHIP WRECK AND I WAS LIKE
WOE, I WAS TRYING TO CONCENTRATE
BUT IT WAS JUST MASSIVE.
I LOOK DOWN AND SEE THIS
MASSIVE SHIP WRECK BELOW
AND I'M JUST BLOWN AWAY,
THERE IS NO WORDS TO
DESCRIBE HOW AMAZING
THAT EXPERIENCE WAS.
WE ALL JUST SCOOP DOWN THE
ROPE AND AS WE GO DOWN AND
DOWN AND DOWN ITS BREATH TAKING.
THE FATE OF THE ROAN BEGAN
WITH THE YELLOW FEVER
OUTBREAK IN 1867 ON ST. THOMAS.
WITH THE DISEASE RAPID THE
CAPTAIN STAYED AWAY FROM
REFUELING AT PORT AND TOOK
ON COAL FROM ANOTHER
SHIP NOT FAR FROM THEM.
AS AN APPROACHING
HURRICANE TOOK AIM ON THE
ISLAND THE ROAN MADE A
BREAK FOR DEEPER WATER
TO RIDE OUT THE STORM.
SHE PASSED TOO CLOSE TO THE ROCK
OFF SALT ISLAND AND SUFFERED A
DISASTROUS SPLIT IN THE HULL.
COOL WATER SPILLED INTO
STEAM ENGINES GOING AT
FULL POWER RESULTING IN A
MASSIVE EXPLOSION
THAT LITERALLY BLEW
THE SHIP IN HALF.
SINKING HER
ALMOST INSTANTLY.
AFTER AN INCREDIBLE 40
MINUTES BELOW THE SURFACE
EXPLORING THE WRECK IT WAS
TIME TO COME UP, ENDING
AN EXPERIENCE GINA, KATIE
AND I WOULD NEVER FORGET.
GINA WHAT DID YOU THINK?
IT WAS AMAZING.
YOU GUYS LOOKED
GREAT DOWN THERE.
LOOKED LIKE PROS.
OH MY GOD SO COOL.
SO COOL.
THAT WAS THE COOLEST DANG
THING I'VE EVER DONE.
UP NEXT ITS TIME TO SET SAIL
AGAIN AS WE SET COURSE FOR
ANOTHER AMAZING ISLAND IN
THE BVIS AND WE DISCOVER
ANOTHER PART OF THE ISLAND
THAT TOOK US ALL BY SURPRISE.
WOW, THIS IS AMAZING.
WHEN MOTION RETURNS.
[ Female Announcer ]
What would you call
an ordinary breakfast pastry
that's been wrapped
in a flaky crust
stuffed with a gooey center
toasted up all golden brown
then given a delicious design?
A toaster strudel.
Pillsbury Toaster Strudel.
So Delicious...So Fun.
[ Female Announcer ]
GO FROM ZERO TO PIZZA
IN JUST 60 SECONDS
WITH TOTINO'S PIZZA ROLLS
AND GRAB A BITE OF
SNACK-DEFYING, SATISFYING...
BECAUSE PIZZA...NEVER...MISSES.
IT'S ON. LET'S ROLL.
IN THE CLEAR
THAT'S ENOUGH VERTICAL.
(LAUGHTER) WERE SAILING
THE BRITISH VIRGIN ISLAND
WITH TWO MOTION GUEST
HIKERS ON CATY WAMPA AND
43 FOOT CATAMARAN, BOATS
LIKE THIS CAN BE CHARTERED
WITH A CAPTAIN IF YOU
DON'T KNOW HOW TO SAIL.
BUT THE MOTION CREW IS
SAILING THIS VESSEL
OURSELVES TO EXPLORE THE
SPECTACULAR BEAUTY
OF THESE ISLANDS.
AFTER AN INCREDIBLE DIVE
ON THE WRECK OF THE RMS
ROAN NEAR SALT ISLAND WE
SET A COURSE FOR ONE OF
THE SMALLER ISLANDS IN
THE CHAIN, VIRGIN CORDA.
WITH STEADY WINDS TO THE
EAST, AND 20 MILE RUN TO
SABA ROCK IN THE NORTH SOUND
WE HOISTED SAILS, CUT THE
ENGINES, AND BEGAN OUR FIRST
TECHNICAL ROUTE IN THE WIND.
SAIL BOATS CAN MOVE
INTO THE WIND USING
ANGLES CALLED TACKING.
THE WINDS ENERGY IS
TRANSFERRED INTO THE SAILS
PROPELLING THE BOAT BACK
INTO THE GENERAL DIRECTION
THE WIND IS COMING FROM.
PREDICTING THESE ANGLES
FOLLOWING THE SAILS IS
WHAT MAKES THIS SO FUN.
SO WHEN JOHN CUT THE
DIESEL ENGINES AND WE
SAW THE SAILS WERE UP.
IT'S A REALLY PEACEFUL
EXPERIENCE, EVERY MORNING
WE WOULD WAKE UP TO THE
SOUND OF THE ENGINE, AND I
WOULD ONLY WANT TO GET UP
ONCE I KNEW THE SAILS WERERD THE
E UP, SO WHEN I HEARD THE
ENGINE CUT OFF THAT'S WHEN
I WOULD RISE OUT OF BED,
THEN LIKE OKAY I'M READY
FOR THIS EXPERIENCE.
AFTER A GREAT FIVE HOUR
RUN IN THE SOUND WE
TIED UP AT SABA ROCK.
AS ANOTHER DAY ON THE BRITISH
VIRGIN ISLANDS CAME TO THE END E
WERE GRACED WITH ANOTHER
SPECTACULAR SUNSET AND
ENJOYED THE LAID BACK FEEL OF
THE CARIBBEAN.
IN THE MORNING WE UNTIED
EARLY AND HEADED BACK TO
THE SOUTH TO A POPULAR
DESTINATION
CALLED THE BATHS.
THIS LARGE OUTCROPPING OF
BOULDERS HAS CREATED A
MAZE LIKE GROTTO FILLED
WITH CARIBBEAN
WATERS AND PAINTED
WITH DAZZLING LIGHT.
JUST A MAZE GOING THROUGH
HERE, EVEN THOUGH THERE
ARE A LOT OF PEOPLE YOU
CAN GET AWAY FROM THEM
IN NOOKS AND CRANNIES.
♪ MUSIC
THE WORLD IS
FILLED WITH TROPICAL
DESTINATION LIKE THE
PROTECTED WATER WAYS AND
GENTLE WINDS OF THE
BRITISH VIRGIN ISLAND MAKE
A SAILING HERE A SAFE
AND FUN WAY TO EXPLORE.
WHAT'S REALLY SPECIAL ABOUT THE
BRITISH VIRGIN ISLANDS IS A GRET
PLACE FOR SAILING.
IT'S A VERY EASY SAILING
AREA SO IT'S SUITABLE FOR
PEOPLE WITH RELATIVELY A
SMALL AMOUNT
OF EXPERIENCE.
THE THING ABOUT CONCH
CHARTERS IS IT'S A FAMILY
BUSINESS, WERE OWNER
OPERATED AND ALL THE
OWNERS STILL WORK
IN THE BUSINESS.
WERE 25 YEARS OLD
NOW SO WE'VE BEEN
AROUND FOR A WHILE.
MOST OF OUR BOATS COME FOR
MOORINGS OR SUN SAIL AND THE
OWNERS MOVE THEM ACROSS TO US.
WE MAINTAIN THE BOATS THE OWNERS
CHARTER THEM OUT AND PEOPLE SAIL
AT A REASONABLE PRICE.
WE REALLY ENJOYED
THE UNIQUE EXPERIENCE
WITH KATIE AND GINA.
SAILING ISN'T FOR
EVERYBODY BUT WE REALLY
LOVED THE LAID BACK, GO AT
YOUR OWN PACE, GO
WHERE EVER YOU WANT TO FREEDOM,
SAILING GAVE US.
THIS HAS BEEN SUCH AN
INCREDIBLE THING AND I
FEEL SO BLESSED TO BE ABLE
TO EXPERIENCE THIS, AND DO
EVERYTHING WITH MY FRIEND
AND TO MEET YOU GUYS I SEE
ON TV AND JUST
HANG OUT, IT WAS,
ITS WAS INCREDIBLE.
I STILL CANT BELIEVE IT.
AND EVERY MORNING WAKING UP AND
HAVING EVERYTHING PREPARED FOR N
AWESOME EXPERIENCE.
THERE WASN'T A MINUTE YOU HAVE
TO PLAN OR HAVE TO DO ANYTHING T
WAS JUST EVERYTHING'S TAKEN
CARE OF AND THE MOTION CREW
JUST WANTS YOU TO HAVE AN
AMAZING RAW AWESOME EXPERIENCE.
SO THAT'S AN OPPORTUNITY
YOU WONT GET ANYWHERE OUTSIDE
THIS TELEVISION PROGRAM.
WE HAD AN AMAZING TIME SAILING
AND EXPLORING THE BEAUTY OF THE
BRITISH VIRGIN ISLANDS.
FOR MORE INFORMATION
ON EXPLORING THE BVIS
VISIT LIVEWELLNETWORK.COM
AND CLICK OR SEARCH MOTION AND
REMEMBER TO JOIN THE MOTION CREW
ON THE ROAD OR THE WATER
CHECK OUT OUR FACEBOOK FANPAGE
WEYou know how much Grandma.
wanted to be here
for your fist Christmas?
You see
Grandma lives waaaay down here,
and you live way up here.
Brian, your cousin, he's
a little bit older than you,
he lives here, in Chicago.
And your Aunt Lisa lives here,
in Baltimore.
Uncle Earnie?
Waaay out in Hawaii.
But don't you worry,
we will always be together
for Christmas.
[ Male Announcer ]
Being together
is the best part
of the holidays
and Cheerios is happy
to be part of the family.
You just ate Dallas!
GOOD MORNING, HARRIS FAMILY!
AFTER A TRAGIC WAR INJURY,
A VETERAN COMES HOME
TO INSPIRE HIS FELLOW SOLDIERS.
Shilo: MY VEHICLE WAS HIT
BY A BOMB IN THE ROAD.
Ty: SHILO WAS SEVERELY BURNED
IN IRAQ.
THREE AMERICAN HEROES
WERE KILLED THAT DAY.
I WONDER WHY I'M HERE
AND THEY'RE NOT.
BUT NO MATTER HOW MUCH PAIN
HE'S BEEN THROUGH,
IT HASN'T STOPPED HIM FROM
VISITING OTHER WOUNDED WARRIORS
AND MOTIVATING THEM
TO KEEP FIGHTING.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Paige: WE'RE TEAMING UP
SO THAT WE CAN HELP
EVEN MORE WOUNDED VETERANS.
WE HAVE RAISED $1.1 MILLION!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
YOU GUYS ARE GONNA GET TO SEE
YOUR FRIEND J.R. MARTINEZ.
HOW'S EVERYTHING?
MOVE THAT BUS!