ROLLING STONES FRONT MAN, MICK
JAGGER.
AN APPARENT JOKE THAT NO ONE'S
LAUGHING AT RIGHT NOW.
>>> GOOD MORNING, EVERYBODY.
HAPPY FRIDAY.
WE DO BEGIN TODAY WITH BREAKING
NEWS.
WORD OF DEEPENING U.S. MILITARY
INVOLVEMENT IN THE FACE OF FEARS
THAT THE BLOODY SYRIA WILL SPILL
OVER THAT COUNTRY'S BORDERS.
>> REPORTS THIS MORNING SAY
DEFENSE SECRETARY, LEON PANETTA
HAS SIGNED THE ORDER TO SEND 2
PATRIOT MISSILE BATTERIES, AS
WELL AS 400 AMERICAN TROOPS, TO
TURKEY.
THEY'RE BEING DEPLOYED TO HELP
PROTECT TURKEY AGAINST A
POSSIBLE MISSILE ATTACK OR
CHEMICAL WEAPONS FROM SYRIA.
AND THE MOVES COMES AS
INTERNATIONAL SUPPORT FOR
SYRIA'S RUTHLESS DICTATOR IS
FADING.
THE HEAD OF NATO SAYS THE
COLLAPSE OF BASHAR AL ASSAD'S
REGIME IS JUST A MATTER OF TIME.
AND THERE ARE CONFLICTING
REPORTS THAT HIS MOST POWERFUL
ALLY, RUSSIA,
MAY BE PREPARING FOR HIS DEFEAT.
REBELS ARE GAINING GROUND
OUTSIDE THE CAPITAL AND HAVE
DEFIED EVERY EFFORT TO DEFEAT
THEM.
>>> THERE'S SOME CONFUSION OVER
WHERE FORMER SOUTH AFRICAN
PRESIDENT NELSON MANDELA IS
BEING TREATED.
GOVERNMENT OFFICIALS THERE SAY
THEY ARE PROTECTING HIS PRIVACY
NOT CONFIRMING WHICH HOSPITAL IS
TREATING HIM.
>> THE 94-YEAR-OLD
ANTI-APARTHEID ICON WAS ADMITTED
ON SATURDAY FOR WHAT HAS SINCE
BEEN DIAGNOSED AS A LUNG
INFECTION.
>>> IN OTHER NEWS RIGHT NOW,
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL HAVE TO GO
TO PLAN "B," TO FIND A NEW
SECRETARY OF STATE.
>> IN A SURPRISE MOVE, U.N.
AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE WITHDREW
HER NAME FROM CONSIDERATION,
SAYING THE COUNTRY WOULD NOT
BENEFIT FROM A BITTER, COSTLY
CONFIRMATION PROCESS.
>> SEVERAL REPUBLICANS MADE IT
CLEAR THEY DID NOT WANT RICE TO
BE THE NATION'S TOP DIPLOMAT.
AND ABC'S TAHMAN BRADLEY JOINS
US, NOW LIVE, FROM WASHINGTON
WITH MORE ON THIS SURPRISE MOVE.
HI, TAHMAN.
>> Reporter: HELLO.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU, ROB AND
PAULA.
THE PRESIDENT'S ANNOUNCEMENT OF
HIS NEW NATIONAL SECURITY TEAM
COULD COME ANY DAY NOW.
AND WITH SUSAN RICE OUT OF THE
RUNNING, WE'RE GETTING A CLEARER
PICTURE OF THE TOP CONTENDERS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S NEW NATIONAL
SECURITY TEAM IS TAKING SHAPE.
FIRST, SECRETARY OF STATE.
U.N. AMBASSADOR, SUSAN RICE, WHO
HAS BEEN AT THE CENTER OF
CONTROVERSY OVER THE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION'S HANDLING OF THE
ATTACK ON THE U.S. CONSULATE IN
LIBYA, PULLED HER NAME OUT OF
CONTENTION.
TELLING NBC, SHE DOESN'T WANT TO
BE A DISTRACTION.
>> I DIDN'T WANT TO SEE A
CONFIRMATION PROCESS THAT WAS
VERY PROLONGED, VERY
POLITICIZED, VERY DISTRACTING
AND VERY DISRUPTIVE.
>> Reporter: WITH RICE NO LONGER
IN THE RUNNING, SENATOR JOHN
KERRY OF MASSACHUSETTS SEEMS THE
PRESIDENT'S LIKELY PICK.
>> I HAVE NO COMMENTS ON THE
PROCESS.
>> Reporter: NEXT, SECRETARY OF
DEFENSE.
SENATOR KERRY'S NAME WAS FLOATED
FOR THE JOB.
BUT SENATOR CHUCK HAGEL, A
VIETNAM VETERAN AND A
REPUBLICAN, WHO BECAME A CRITIC
OF THE IRAQ WAR, SEEMS TO HAVE
THE EDGE.
THERE'S ALSO THE TOP JOB AT THE
CIA.
THE ACTING DIRECTOR, MICHAEL
MORRELL, AND WHITE HOUSE
COUNTERTERRORISM ADVISER
JOHN BRENNAN ARE CONSIDERED TOP
CONTENDERS.
AS THE DOMINOS FALL, THERE'S AN
INTERESTING POLITICAL ANGLE.
IF SENATOR KERRY IS TAPPED FOR A
CABINET POST, OUTGOING
MASSACHUSETTS SENATOR, SCOTT
BROWN, IS WIDELY EXPECTED TO RUN
IN THE SPECIAL ELECTION TO FILL
KERRY'S SEAT.
>> VICTORY AND DEFEAT IS
TEMPORARY.
WE MAY, OBVIOUSLY, MEET AGAIN.
>> Reporter: BROWN CAME TO POWER
IN A 2010 SPECIAL ELECTION TO
FILL SENATOR TED KENNEDY'S OLD
SEAT, BUT LOST RE-ELECTION IN
NOVEMBER TO ELIZABETH WARREN.
MANY SAID SENATOR KERRY WAS
BREEZE THROUGH NOMINATION AS
SECRETARY OF STATE.
BUT HE MAY FACE TOUGH QUESTIONS
ABOUT HIS PAST SUPPORT OF SYRIAN
PRESIDENT BASHAR AL ASSAD.
ROB AND PAULA?
>> ABC'S TAHMAN BRADLEY LIVE IN
WASHINGTON.
THANKS, TAHMAN.
>>> AND THE ADMINISTRATION'S
ASIA TEAM IS REPORTED TO HAVE
BEEN SO SURPRISED BY NORTH
KOREA'S ROCKET LAUNCH THIS WEEK,
SEVERAL OF THEM WERE AT A
HOLIDAY PARTY WHEN IT HAPPENED.
A BLOG ON THE FOREIGN POLICY
WEBSITE REPORTS THEY WERE JOKING
IT WAS NICE OF THE NORTH KOREANS
TO DELAY THE LAUNCH SO THE PARTY
WOULDN'T BE INTERRUPTED.
THE STATE DEPARTMENT, HOWEVER,
DENIES THAT THEY WERE CAUGHT OFF
GUARD.
>>> THE GOVERNORS OF NEW YORK,
NEW JERSEY AND CONNECTICUT, ARE
URGING CONGRESS TO APPROVE A $60
BILLION AID PACKAGE FOR VICTIMS
OF SUPERSTORM SANDY BEFORE THEY
BREAK FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
NEARLY SEVEN WEEKS, NOW, AFTER
THE STORM, MANY FLOODED-OUT
RESIDENTS ARE WAITING FOR FUNDS
TO REPAIR THEIR HOMES.
MORE THAN 100 CEOs ARE ALSO
CALLING ON LAWMAKERS TO ACT
QUICKLY.
BUT REPUBLICANS SAY THE BILL IS
LOADED WITH MANY THINGS THAT
SIMPLY HAVE NOTHING TO DO WITH
THE STORM.
>>> WELL, 18 DAYS, NOW, AND
COUNTING.
AND THERE ARE MORE SIGNS OF SLOW
PROGRESS BEING MADE TO AVOID
THAT FISCAL CLIFF.
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER MET AT THE
WHITE HOUSE FOR LESS THAN AN
HOUR YESTERDAY.
BOTH SIDES SAID THEY HAD A,
QUOTE, FRANK DISCUSSION.
AND THE LINES OF COMMUNICATION
REMAIN OPEN.
AMERICANS WILL BE HIT WITH
AUTOMATIC TAX HIKES AND BUDGET
CUTS UNLESS A DEAL IS REACHED BY
JANUARY 1st.
>>> AND STATE GOVERNMENTS MUST
DECIDE BY TODAY IF THEY WILL RUN
THEIR OWN INSURANCE EXCHANGES
UNDER THE NEW HEALTH CARE LAW.
THOSE EXCHANGES WILL SERVE
MILLIONS OF UNINSURED AMERICANS
IN UNDER A YEAR, 2014.
19 STATES HAVE DECIDED TO
ESTABLISH INSURANCE.
17 STATES, AS WELL AS THE
DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA, HAVE SAID
THEY WILL ENROLL IN THE FEDERAL
PROGRAM.
EIGHT STATES WANT A PARTNERSHIP
WITH THE FED.
SIX STATES HAVE MADE NO DECISION
AND HAVE UNTIL TODAY TO DO SO.
>>> A SHOPPING MALL THAT BECAME
THE SCENE OF A DEADLY SHOOTING
SPREE IS SET TO REOPEN IN OREGON
THIS MORNING.
TWO PEOPLE WERE KILLED WHEN
22-YEAR-OLD JACOB ROBERTS OPENED
FIRE IN THE FOOD COURT OF THE
CLACKAMAS TOWN CENTER ON
TUESDAY.
A 15-YEAR-OLD GIRL WAS ALSO
SERIOUSLY WOUNDED.
ROBERTS, THEN, OF COURSE, TOOK
HIS OWN LIFE.
A CANDLELIGHT VIGIL FOR THE
VICTIMS IS SET FOR TONIGHT.
>>> AND PEOPLE ACROSS SAN DIEGO
WOKE UP TO AN UNUSUAL DELUGE.
SEVERAL INCHES OF RAIN MAKING A
REAL MESS OUT OF THE MORNING
COMMUTE.
>> THE DOWNPOURS FLOODED
BUSINESSES, AS WELL AS MAJOR
INTERSECTIONS, LEAVING DRIVERS
STRANDED IN THE ROAD.
SOME PEOPLE EVEN HAD TO BE
RESCUED FROM THOSE FLOODWATERS.
>>> AND JUST NORTH OF SAN DIEGO,
ALL THAT RAIN LOOSENED A GIANT
BOULDER.
LOOK AT THAT THING.
IT TUMBLED DOWN A HILLSIDE AND
PUNCHED A GAPING HOLE THROUGH
SOMEONE'S GARAGE.
THE HUGE ROCK CRUSHED EVERYTHING
FROM CHRISTMAS ORNAMENTS TO
TOOLS.
THE HOMEOWNER WAS SHAKEN UP BUT
THANKFUL SHE WASN'T IN THE
GARAGE WHEN THAT BOULDER HIT.
>> THEY HAVE FALLING ROCK
INSURANCE.
>>> TIME, NOW, FOR THE WEATHER
FROM ACROSS THE NATION.
SHOWERS FROM SAN DIEGO UP TO
SEATTLE.
HEAVY RAIN IN LAS VEGAS, PHOENIX
AND ALBUQUERQUE.
MORE THAN A FOOT OF MOUNTAIN
SNOW FROM ARIZONA TO SOUTHERN
UTAH.
THUNDERSTORMS AROUND WICHITA,
OKLAHOMA CITY AND DALLAS.
>> 70s IN DALLAS, AND
NEW ORLEANS.
MOSTLY 40s IN THE NORTHEAST,
MIDWEST AND PACIFIC NORTHWEST.
>>> WELL, COMING UP,
IT IS VERY GOOD TO BE AN INTERN
AT FACEBOOK.
AND WE'LL TELL YOU WHY.
YOU JUST GAVE IT AWAY.
>>> PLUS, HOLIDAY TRAVEL.
NEW AND ENCOURAGING ESTIMATES
ABOUT HOW MANY OF US ARE ABOUT
TO BE ON THE MOVE.
>>> AND THAT HORRIFIC STORY FROM
CHICAGO.
A MAN'S FATAL DECISION TO GET UP
ON THAT SMOKESTACK.
STAY WITH US.
[ Female Announcer ] NOW GET
HIGH SPEED INTERNET AT HOME
ON OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network,
A CONNECTION YOU CAN COUNT ON.
INTRODUCING AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET
WITH MORE SPEED OPTIONS,
RELIABILITY
AND Wi-Fi HOT SPOTS THAN EVER.
GO TO OUR WEBSITE BELOW TO GET
U-verse HIGH SPEED INTERNET
FOR JUST 14.95 A MONTH
FOR 12 MONTHS WITH
A ONE-YEAR PRICE GUARANTEE.
IT'S ALL THE SPEED YOU NEED
ALL AT A GREAT PRICE.
OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network
GIVES YOU MORE
OF WHAT YOU ENJOY ONLINE.
AND WITH AT&T,
OUR WIRELESS GATEWAY
TURNS YOUR HOME
INTO A PRIVATE Wi-Fi HOT SPOT
THAT CONNECTS
YOUR Wi-Fi DEVICES
AND CAN EVEN SAVE ON YOUR
SMART PHONE DATA USAGE AT HOME.
GO TO OUR WEBSITE BELOW
TO GET AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET
FOR JUST 14.95 A MONTH
FOR 12 MONTHS WITH
A ONE-YEAR PRICE GUARANTEE.
THAT INCLUDES ACCESS ON-THE-GO
TO OUR ENTIRE NATIONAL
Wi-Fi HOT SPOT NETWORK,
WITH OVER 30,000 HOT SPOTS.
AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET.
NOW ON OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network,
A CONNECTION YOUR WHOLE HOUSE
CAN COUNT ON.
♪
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYONE.
AMERICANS ARE GETTING READY TO
SPEND PLENTY OF MONEY ON HOLIDAY
TRAVEL.
AAA PREDICTS THIS IS GOING TO BE
THE BUSIEST CHRISTMAS TRAVEL
SEASON IN SIX YEARS, WITH MORE
THAN 93 MILLION AMERICANS ON THE
MOVE.
MOST BY CAR.
ONE IN FOUR WILL DRIVE AT LEAST
50 MILES.
AND GAS PRICES COULD DROP TO
WHERE THEY WERE LAST YEAR.
AN AVERAGE OF $3.23 A GALLON.
>>> PEOPLE ARE ALSO OPENING UP
THEIR WALLETS AT STORES AND
ONLINE.
RETAIL SALES ROSE IN NOVEMBER.
THE INCREASE LOOKS SLIGHT, 0.3%.
BUT TAKING OUT THE BIG DROP IN
GAS PRICES, RETAIL SALES ARE UP
A SOLID 0.8%.
THERE WAS STRONG DEMAND FOR
ELECTRONICS AND CARS.
>>> PEOPLE ARE DOING A GOOD JOB
FOR PAYING FOR ALL THOSE THINGS
WHEN THE CREDIT CARD BILL COMES
DUE.
A NEW FROST FROM TRANSUNION SAYS
THE CREDIT CARD DELINQUENCY
RATE, BORROWERS WHO ARE 90 DAYS
FOR MORE BEHIND, SHOULD STAY LOW
NEXT YEAR, WHERE IT IS NOW, LESS
THAN 1%.
>>> AMERICA'S BIGGEST AUTOMAKER
IS PUTTING NEW ATTENTION ON SOME
OF ITS BIGGEST VEHICLES.
GENERAL MOTORS HAS RELEASED
THEIR NEW SILVERADO AND GMC
PICKUP TRUCKS.
LOOKING TO CRASH IN ON THE
GROWING DEMAND FOR FULL-SIZE
TRUCKS.
THE REBOUND IN HOUSING AND
CONSTRUCTION IS HELPING FUEL THE
STRENGTH IN TRUCK SALES.
>>> THE iPHONE 5 FINALLY WENT ON
SALE TODAY, IN THE WORLD'S
BIGGEST SMARTPHONE MARKET,
CHINA.
THAT COUNTRY IS HUGELY IMPORTANT
TO APPLE, WHICH HAS SEEN ITS
STOCK PRICE SLIDE LATELY.
ONLY THE U.S., IN FACT, BUYS
MORE APPLE PRODUCTS.
AND CHINA ACCOUNTED FOR ALMOST
$24 BILLION OR ABOUT 15% OF
APPLE'S REVENUES IN THE PAST
YEAR.
>>> AND IT'S NO SECRET THAT
APPLE AND OTHER TECH COMPANIES
PAY WELL.
IT TURNS OUT EVEN THEIR INTERNS
ARE SCORING BIG BUCKS AT
FACEBOOK.
>> BUSINESS INSIDER REPORTS
FACEBOOK PAYS INTERNS MORE THAN
$5,600 A MONTH.
AND THAT ENDS UP BEING ABOUT
$67,000 A YEAR, YEP, FOR BEING
AN INTERN.
THAT'S ABOUT $25,000 MORE THAN
THE AVERAGE U.S. WORKER MAKES.
>> HERE'S YOUR APPLICATION.
AND I PRINTED ONE OUT FOR ME.
>>> WHEN WE COME BACK, THE
GUESTS WHO GOT A LOT MORE THAN
THEY EXPECTED AT ONE GOLDEN
CORRAL.
>>> AND SOME SAD FACES THIS
MORNING IN PHILADELPHIA, AFTER
YET ANOTHER DISAPPOINTING
PERFORMANCE BY THOSE EAGLES.
Introducing NOOK HD -
the world's best 7" tablet made
for reading and entertainment.
Your favorite magazines and
catalogs look better than ever.
And with scrapbooking,
you can save the
things you love,
bring them all together,
And be inspired like
never before.
Scrapbooking. Create
yours with Nook HD -
and even bigger with HD+.
Find yours at Barnes & Noble.
PRETTY SWEET, HUH?
CUTE.
BUT DON'T YOU HAVE ANY APPS
ON YOUR PHONE
THAT CAN MAKE YOUR LIFE
EASIER?
WHO DO YOU THINK I AM,
Quicken Loans?
AT Quicken Loans, WE'LL PROVIDE
YOU WITH MYQL MOBILE.
THIS AMAZINGLY USEFUL APP
ALLOWS YOU
TO TAKE PICTURES
OF YOUR MORTGAGE DOCUMENTS
USING AN iPhone
OR Android SMART PHONE...
SO YOU CAN EASILY
SEND THEM TO US.
ONE MORE WAY Quicken Loans
IS Engineered to Amaze.
OOH, LA-LA!
>>> THE SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA
MOUNTAINS ARE BURIED UNDER A
FRESH COAT OF SNOW THIS MORNING.
AND IT'S STILL COMING DOWN.
TIRE CHAINS WERE MANDATORY FOR
DRIVERS HEADING INTO MOUNTAIN
PASSES AND RESORTS.
EVEN WITH THE CHAINS, THEY SAY
THE ROADS WILL -- WERE STILL
TREACHEROUS.
>>> NOW, FOR A LOOK AT MORNING
ROAD CONDITIONS.
SLICK AT TIMES FROM SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA TO SEATTLE.
RAIN DRENCHES ROADS FROM VEGAS,
TO ALBUQUERQUE.
WET HIGHWAYS FROM TEXAS TO
KANSAS.
>> IF YOU'RE FLYING TODAY,
AIRPORT DELAYS ARE POSSIBLE IN
L.A., VEGAS, PHOENIX AND DALLAS.
>>> TRAGIC STORY, NOW.
A YOUNG MAN TRYING TO TAKE A
PICTURE OF THE CHICAGO SKYLINE
PLUNGED 22 FEET DOWN A
SMOKESTACK.
HE AND HIS GIRLFRIEND HAD
CLIMBED TO THE ROOF OF THE
HISTORIC INTERCONTINENTAL HOTEL,
MORE THAN 40 STORIES UP.
AND WHEN HE WENT UP A LADDER TO
THE TOP OF THAT SMOKESTACK AND
LOST HIS FOOTING.
>> HE SPOKE TO FIREFIGHTERS AND
TALKED TO HIS GIRLFRIEND ON HIS
CELL PHONE.
BUT THEN, LOST CONSCIOUSNESS.
>> THE BEST WAY TO GET HIM OUT
WAS GO ABOUT TWO FLOORS BELOW.
AND WE HAD TO CUT THE DUCTWORK
FOR THE CHIMNEY, WHICH WAS MADE
OUT OF STEEL.
WE EVENTUALLY ENDED UP SLIDING
THE VICTIM DOWN INTO THE HOLE.
AND REMOVING HIM FROM THE
BUILDING.
>> Reporter: FIRST RESPONDERS
WORKED FOUR HOURS TRYING TO FREE
THE MAN.
BUT BY THE TIME THEY REACHED
HIM, IT WAS TOO LATE.
HE WAS DECLARED DEAD AT A
HOSPITAL JUST A SHORT TIME
LATER.
>>> AND A FRIGHTENING ATTACK IN
DENVER, WHERE FOUR PEOPLE WERE
SET ON FIRE.
POLICE SAY TWO MEN SPRAYED
LIQUID ON THE VICTIMS AFTER A
WOMAN OPENED HER APARTMENT DOOR
LAST NIGHT.
THE MEN THEN THREW A MATCH OR
LIGHTER ON THEM.
ONE PERSON WAS BADLY HURT.
THE OTHERS ARE BEING TREATED FOR
MINOR BURNS.
>>> AND A POPULAR CHAIN
RESTAURANT MAY BE TO BLAME FOR A
VIRUS OUTBREAK, SPREADING
THROUGH CASPER, WYOMING.
HEALTH INSPECTORS SAY ABOUT 200
CUSTOMERS BECAME SICK AFTER
EATING AT THE GOLDEN CORRAL
BUFFET.
PUBLIC HEALTH EXPERTS BELIEVE
THE RESTAURANT IS CONTAMINATED
WITH THE NOROVIRUS.
THE RESTAURANT IS CLOSING ITS
DOORS FOR 24 HOURS TO BE CLEANS
AND DISINFECTED.
>>> THE NURSE THAT KILLED
HERSELF AFTER FIELDING THE PRANK
CALL AT KATE MIDDLETON'S
HOSPITAL ROOM, WILL BE
MEMORIALIZED TODAY.
SHE WAS FOUND HANGING BY A
SCARF.
SHE LEFT THREE APPARENT SUICIDE
NOTES.
ONE OF THEM CRITICIZED
COLLEAGUES AT THE HOSPITAL FOR
HER TREATMENT AFTER THE
INCIDENT.
>>> ALSO, SINGER JENNI RIVERA
HAS COME HOME.
MEXICAN OFFICIALS RELEASED THE
SINGER'S REMAINS TO HER FAMILY.
AND THEY FLEW HER HOME ON A
CHARTER'S JET.
RIVERA DIED SUNDAY WHEN HER
PLANE CRASHED INTO A MOUNTAINOUS
AREA OF MEXICO AND NEARLY
DISSINT RATED.
TWO POLICE OFFICERS ARE BEING
ARRESTED FOR STEALING FROM THE
CRASH SITE AND LEAKING PHOTOS TO
THE MEDIA.
>>> A BLOCKBUSTER MOVE, THE TEAM
HAS SIGNED JOSH HAMILTON TO A
FIVE-YEAR DEAL WORTH 125 MILLION
BUCKS.
HAMILTON, WHO PLAYED FOR THE
RANGERS LAST SEASON, IS
CONSIDERED ONE OF THE BEST
PLAYERS IN THE GAME.
HE JOINS A ROSTER THAT ALSO
INCLUDES ALBERTS -- AND --
>> PITCHER SANK GREINKE.
>> I DON'T FOLLOW BASEBALL.
>> ALBERT PUJOLS IS ONE OF THE
BIGGEST NAMES.
>>> TWO WEEKS AFTER COLLEGE
FOOTBALL'S REGULAR SEASON ENDED,
THE BOWL SEASON IS ABOUT TO KICK
OFF.
2 OF THE 35 BOWL GAMES TOMORROW.
30 AND UP.
>> SOME OF THE SPORTS HIGHLIGHTS
FROM LAST NIGHT FROM ESPN.
>> DOUG KEZIRIAN HERE WITH YOUR
"SPORTSCENTER" UPDATE.
WE START UNDER THE LIGHTS AT
MADISON SQUARE GARDEN IN
PRIMETIME.
THE LAKERS VISITING THE KNICKS.
NEW YORK UNDEFEATED AT HOME THIS
SEASON.
19-1, AT HOME, UNDER MIKE
WOODSON.
FIRST QUARTER, KNICKS, BLAZING
HOT.
ESPECIALLY CARMELO ANTHONY.
KNOCKING DOWN HIS FIRST THREE
FROM DISTANCE.
THEN, MELO, TAKING IT TO THE
ROCK.
JAMMING OVER JORDAN HILL.
KNICKS UP NINE.
THEN, FLOWING PAST KOBE BRYANT
AND ANTON JAMISON FOR THE HOOP
AND THE HORN.
22 IN THE FIRST QUARTER.
THAT'S A CAREER-HIGH.
FIRST QUARTER, SCARY MOMENT FOR
MELO.
FOULED HARD BY DWIGHT HOWARD.
INJURED HIS ANKLE.
LISTED DAY-TO-DAY.
HE FINISHED 10 OF 15 FROM THE
FIELD.
CLOSING MINUTES, RAYMOND FELTON,
THE ALLEY-OOP TO TYSON CHANDLER.
KNICKS REMAIN PERFECT AT HOME.
L.A. FALL TO 9-14.
>>> THURSDAY NIGHT FOOTBALL.
BENGAL, TRYING TO REMAIN IN THE
PLAYOFF HUNT, VISITING PHILLY.
ANDY DALTON, CALLED HIS OWN
NUMBER.
GETS INTO THE END ZONE.
CINCY TRAILED 13-10, AT THE
BREAK.
BUT ALL-BENGALS IN THE SECOND
HALF.
NEXT PHILLY POSSESSION, FUMBLES.
GILBERRY RECOVERS.
25 YARDS.
THE BIG FELLA SCORES A
TOUCHDOWN.
FIVE TURNOVERS IN THE GAME FOR
THE EAGLES.
BENGALS GO ON TOP, 24-13.
LATER, DALTON TO A.J. GREEN.
HIS 11th RECEIVING TOUCHDOWN.
BENGALS WIN 34-13.
AND ARE BACK IN THE PLAYOFF
HUNT.
CURRENTLY IN THAT WILD CARD
POSITION.
BUT EVERYTHING CAN CHANGE THIS
SUNDAY.
>>> SPEAKING OF CHANGE, ZACH
GREINKE WENT TO THE DODGERS.
IF JOSH HAMILTON WAS HOPING TO
JOIN HIM, NOT HAPPENING.
>>> UP NEXT, "THE PULSE."
MICK JAGGER, IN THE MIDDLE OF
SOME CONTROVERSIAL, AFTER THE
12-12-12 CONCERT.
>>> AND SOME COUGAR PRIDE.
LOOK AT THAT.
CHRISTMAS COLLEGE STYLE.
STAY WITH US.
WITH  HEARTBEAT.
THE USUAL, BOB?
NOT TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
BOB HAS AFIB:
ATRIAL FIBRILLATION NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
A CONDITION THAT PUTS HIM
AT GREATER RISK FOR A STROKE.
[ GPS ] TURN LEFT.
I DON'T THINK SO.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR YEARS, BOB TOOK WARFARIN,
AND MADE A MONTHLY TRIP TO THE
CLINIC TO GET HIS BLOOD TESTED.
BUT NOT ANYMORE.
BOB'S DOCTOR RECOMMENDED
A DIFFERENT OPTION:
ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
XARELTO® IS THE FIRST AND ONLY
ONCE-A-DAY PRESCRIPTION
BLOOD THINNER
FOR PATIENTS WITH AFIB
NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
THAT DOESN'T REQUIRE
ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING.
LIKE WARFARIN,
XARELTO® IS PROVEN EFFECTIVE
TO REDUCE THE RISK
OF AN AFIB-RELATED STROKE.
THERE IS LIMITED DATA
ON HOW THESE DRUGS COMPARE
WHEN WARFARIN IS WELL MANAGED.
NO ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING
MEANS BOB CAN SPEND HIS
EXTRA TIME HOWEVER HE LIKES.
NEW ZEALAND!
XARELTO®
IS JUST ONE PILL A DAY,
TAKEN WITH THE EVENING MEAL.
AND WITH
NO DIETARY RESTRICTIONS,
BOB CAN EAT THE HEALTHY FOODS
HE LIKES.
DO NOT STOP TAKING
XARELTO® RIVAROXABAN
WITHOUT TALKING TO THE DOCTOR
WHO PRESCRIBES IT FOR YOU.
STOPPING MAY INCREASE YOUR RISK
OF HAVING A STROKE.
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU DEVELOP ANY SIGNS
OR SYMPTOMS OF BLEEDING,
LIKE UNUSUAL BRUISING
OR TINGLING.
YOU MAY HAVE A HIGHER RISK
OF BLEEDING
IF YOU TAKE XARELTO®
WITH ASPIRIN PRODUCTS,
NSAIDS OR BLOOD THINNERS.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE TAKING XARELTO®
IF YOU CURRENTLY HAVE
ABNORMAL BLEEDING.
XARELTO® CAN CAUSE BLEEDING,
WHICH CAN BE SERIOUS,
AND RARELY MAY LEAD TO DEATH.
YOU ARE LIKELY TO BRUISE
MORE EASILY ON XARELTO®,
AND IT MAY TAKE LONGER
FOR BLEEDING TO STOP.
TELL YOUR DOCTORS
YOU ARE TAKING XARELTO®
BEFORE ANY PLANNED MEDICAL
OR DENTAL PROCEDURES.
BEFORE STARTING XARELTO®,
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ANY CONDITIONS,
SUCH AS KIDNEY, LIVER
OR BLEEDING PROBLEMS.
READY TO CHANGE YOUR ROUTINE?
ASK YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
FOR MORE INFORMATION
INCLUDING COST SUPPORT OPTIONS,
CALL 1-888-XARELTO
OR VISIT GOXARELTO.COM.
>>> WELCOME BACK.
IT IS TIME FOR "THE PULSE,"
STORIES YOU'RE GOING TO BE
TALKING ABOUT TODAY.
AND THIS FRIDAY MORNING, IT IS
MICK JAGGER, NOT WHAT HE'S
SINGING.
BUT WHAT HE'S ACTUALLY SAYING.
>> YEAH.
WHEN THE STONES ROCKED THE
12-12-12 SANDY RELIEF CONCERT,
JAGGER MADE A LITTLE JOKE THAT
IS STIRRING UP BIG-TIME
BACKLASH, THOUGH.
HE SAID, QUOTE, IF IT RAINS IN
LONDON, YOU'VE GOT TO COME AND
HELP US, OKAY?
WELL, FANS AROUND HERE WHO KNEW
SANDY WAS A WHOLE LOT MORE THAN
RAIN ARE NOW TAKING TO TWITTER
TO TELL JAGGER.
YOU ASSUME IN HIS MIND IT WAS A
JOKE.
BUT IT DIDN'T PLAY WELL WITH
THAT CROWD, WHO IS VERY MUCH IN
THE MIDST OF THE RECOVERY.
>> A BAD JOKE.
A TASTELESS JOKE.
>>> NOW, THE MUSICAL PART OF
"THE PULSE."
WE START AT THE HOME OF
WASHINGTON STATE UNIVERSITY.
♪
>> THE GUY WHO PUT TOGETHER THAT
LITTLE CHRISTMAS LIGHTS DISPLAY
WORKS AT THE SCHOOL.
THE MUSIC IS THE WASHINGTON
STATE COUGARS FIGHT SONG.
PRETTY GOOD SCHOOL PRIDE THERE,
CONSIDERING THEY JUST FINISHED A
3-9 FOOTBALL SEASON.
PRIDE IS NOT CONDITIONAL.
>> WHATEVER CHEERS THEM UP.
>>> AND FINALLY, A HANUKKAH
TRIBUTE FROM THE HOUSTON
ROCKETS.
>> LISTEN TO THEIR ATTEMPT AT
SINGING THE TRADITIONAL
CHILDREN'S SONG, "I HAVE A
LITTLE DREIDEL."
♪ DREIDEL, DREIDEL
I MADE OUT OF CLAY ♪
♪ AND WHEN IT'S DRY AND READY
THE DREIDEL I SHALL ♪
>> OH.
>> OUCH, GUYS.
OR MAYBE I SHOULD SAY OY VEY.
ROUGH SINGING THERE, GUYS.
STICK THE YOUR DAY JOB.
>> CAN I UNLUG MY --
>> MERCIFULLY, THAT IS OVER.
>> SHOOTING BRICKS, AS WELL.
AT LEAST THEY'RE NOT DOING IT ON
THE BASKETBALL COURT.
>>> FOR SOME OF YOU, YOUR LOCAL
NEWS IS NEXT.
>> FOR EVERYONE ELSE, WE'LL BE
BACK WITH EXTREME PREPARATIONS
FOR "THE HOBBIT."
STAY WITH US, EVERYBODY.
OUS.
ONE DAY GEORGE GOT
AN IMPORTANT LETTER.
HE'S BUILT A ROCKET SHIP
TO TRAVEL INTO SPACE."
GOOGLE, HOW FAR IS EARTH
TO THE MOON?
THE MOON IS 238,900 MILES...
"THE GREAT MOMENT HAD COME."
3, 2, 1...
[ GIGGLING ]
A deep, throbbing,
persistent ache.
My doctor diagnosed it
as fibromyalgia,
thought to be the
result of overactive nerves
that cause chronic
widespread pain.
Lyrica is believed
to calm these nerves.
I learned Lyrica can provide
significant relief
from fibromyalgia pain.
And for some people,
it can work in as early as
the first week of treatment.
So now I can do more of
the things that I enjoy.
Lyrica is not for everyone.
Lyrica may cause serious
allergic reactions
or suicidal thoughts or actions.
Tell your doctor right away
if you have these,
new or worsening depression,
or unusual changes in mood
or behavior,
or any swelling or
affected breathing or skin,
or changes in eyesight,
including blurry vision
or muscle pain with fever
or tired feeling.
Common side effects
are dizziness, sleepiness,
weight gain, and swelling of
hands, legs and feet.
Don't drink alcohol
while taking Lyrica.
Don't drive or use machinery
until you know
how Lyrica affects you.
With less pain,
I'm feeling better
now that I've found Lyrica.
Ask your doctor
if Lyrica is right
for your fibromyalgia pain.
TO OUR KRAFT NATURAL CHEESE
TO MAKE IT CREAMIER.
SO WHATEVER YOU MAKE
ISN'T JUST GOOD, IT'S AMAZING.
♪ LIFE IS AMAZING
WITH THE LOVE THAT I'VE ♪
♪ FOUND
>>> COMING UP NEXT, OVERNIGHT
TWO STRONG QUAKES HIT OFF THE
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA COAST.
FIREFIGHTERS RETURN TO THE
FREMONT METAL PLANT.
PLUS, READY FOR FREEZING
TEMPERATURES AND SERIES OF
STORMS?
>> WE HAVE FROSTY CONDITIONS
THIS MORNING AND THE NEXT COUPLE
OF MORNINGS, TRACKING LIGHT RAIN
FOR TODAY.
BETTER CHANCE FOR TOMORROW AND
CITY.
HEAVY RAIN FROM ALBUQUERQUE TO
VEGAS.
MOUNTAIN SNOW IN THE FOUR
CORNERS.
AND SHOWERS FROM SAN DIEGO TO
SEATTLE.
>>> AND "THE HOBBIT," ONE OF THE
MOST ANTICIPATED MOVIES OF THE
YEARS OPENS NATIONWIDE TODAY.
A LIFELONG FAN BUILT HIS OWN
HOBBIT HOUSE IN PENNSYLVANIA.
IT'S 600 SQUARE FEET.
>> WHILE NOT AS ELABORATE, SOME
FANS WAITING IN CALIFORNIA FOR
TODAY'S PREMIERE, HAVE CREATED A
HOBBIT COMMUNITY OF THEIR VERY
OWN.
HERE'S ROB KABC IN LOS ANGELES.
>> Reporter: THE HOBBIT IS THE
STORY ABOUT 1 WIZARD, 13 DWARVES
AND A HOBBIT.
THE MUCH-ANTICIPATED FILM
VERSION OF THE BOOK WINDS ITS
WAY THROUGH MIDDLE EARTH, ON ITS
WAY TO THEATERS LIKE THIS ONE,
WHERE HOBBIT FANS ARE CAMPING
OUT.
AND IN SOME CASES, CREEPING OUT.
BUT MOSTLY JUST CAMPING OUT.
>> I GOT HERE LAST NIGHT AT
8:40.
IT'S INTERESTING.
I HAVE A GROUP COMING IN LATER.
>> Reporter: AND THERE'S REAL
DEDICATION HERE, CONSIDERING THE
WEATHER.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU BEEN OUT HERE?
>> 24 HOURS, AT LEAST.
>> Reporter: HOW LONG HAS IT
BEEN RAINING?
>> 24 HOURS.
>> I'M HERE FOR THE MOVIE.
AND I'M GOING TO LOVE IT, NO
MATTER WHAT.
♪
>> Reporter: CHRIS DOUGHTY AND
BRIAN SPENT THREE MONTHS
BUILDING THIS HOBBIT HOLE.
COUPLED TOGETHER FOR A COUPLE
HUNDRED BUCKS AND WHATEVER THEY
COULD SCAVENGE FROM THEIR
PARENTS HOME.
THEY VOW TO LIVE IN IT UNTIL THE
BIG PREMIERE.
>> IF YOU'RE GOING TO GO THROUGH
LIFE WITH NO PASSION, LIKE
THAT'S NOT LIFE.
I MEAN, WE'RE KIND OF NERDY.
BUT WE'RE SO INTO THIS.
>> WE ARE SUPERFANS.
GREW OUT MY BEARD ALL YEAR FOR
THIS MOVIE.
OUR LOVING MOTHERS HAVE
CONTRIBUTED GREATLY TO OUR
COSTUMES.
THEY SEWED IT.
>> Reporter: "THE HOBBIT" IS ONE
OF THREE MOVIES THAT WILL COME
FROM THE J.R.R. TOLKIEN BOOK.
THAT MEANS TWO MORE PREMIERES
AND TWO MORE OPPORTUNITIES TO
CAMP OUT AND DRESS UP.
FANS HERE SAY THEY'LL BE BACK,
RAIN OR SHINE, BECAUSE IT'S TOO
HARD TO KICK THE HOBBIT.
IN REDLANDS, ROB HAYES, ABC NEWS
SOUTH, EYEWITNESS NEWS.
>> DEDICATED MOMS.
>>> THAT IS WHAT'S MAKING NEWS
>>> GOOD FRIDAY MORNING,
4:30 A.M. ON WET 14th OF
DECEMBER.
WE GOT A WEEK TO GO IF YOU
BELIEVE THE MAYAN CALENDAR.
>> Kristen: NEW THIS MORNING,
TWO BIG QUAKES RATTLED THE
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA COAST.
THE FIRST IT WAS CENTERED 136
MILES SOUTHWEST OF CATALINA
ISLAND.
FEW SECONDS LATER A 6.1 QUAKE