>> THEY DID NOTHING TO DESERVE
THIS.
>> WHAT TRANSFORMED THIS HIGH
SCHOOL HONOR STUDENT, INTO A
COLD-BLOODED KILLER?
AND BRAND-NEW DETAILS FROM THE
HERO TEACHERS WHO SAVED SO MANY
YOUNG LIVES WITH THEIR QUICK
THINKING.
>> WE WERE COMPLETELY BARRICADED
IN.
>> I THOUGHT WE WERE ALL GOING
TO DIE.
>>> AND SUCH A SAD MORNING HERE
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
I'M JOINED BY ELIZABETH VARGAS
IN NEW YORK.
ELIZABETH, RIGHT BEHIND ME, THE
SANDY HOOK FIREHOUSE, WHERE SO
MANY MOMS AND DADS CAME TO LEARN
ABOUT THEIR CHILDREN.
MANY SLEPT HERE THROUGH THE
NIGHT.
AND THIS HEADLINE RIGHT HERE,
FROM "THE HARTFORD COURANT"
CAPTURES WHAT SO MANY ARE
FEELING HERE TODAY.
OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN.
ALL OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN, OVER
20 LITTLE CHILDREN, AND MORE
ADULTS, DEAD AFTER THE WORST
SHOOTING EVER AT A GRADE SCHOOL.
HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW RIGHT NOW.
THE SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA, 20
YEARS OLD.
HE ALSO SHOT HIS MOTHER BEFORE
COMING TO THE SCHOOL.
SOME BODIES OF THE CHILDREN
SLAIN ARE STILL IN THE SCHOOL.
OTHERS HAVE BEEN REMOVED.
AND FAMILIES WERE NOTIFIED
OVERNIGHT INTO THE MORNING.
THE NAMES OF THE VICTIMS WILL BE
RELEASED THIS MORNING.
WE'RE GOING TO SHOW YOU PICTURES
OF THE VIGIL LAST NIGHT.
YOU SEE THE VIDEO RIGHT THERE.
THE CHURCHES PACKED IN THIS
SMALL TOWN.
PEOPLE PRAYING AND CRYING OVER
THIS HORRENDOUS LOSS, A SCENE OF
SO MUCH GRIEF.
MY "GMA WEEKEND" COLLEAGUE, DAN
HARRIS, IS RIGHT HERE.
YOU'VE BEEN HERE SINCE THE
BEGINNING YESTERDAY.
>> YOU AND I HAVE COVERED WAY
TOO MANY OF THESE DISASTERS.
SORRY, JUST WHEN YOU THINK THE
SHOOTINGS COULDN'T GET WORSE,
JUST WHEN YOU THINK THEY
COULDN'T GET MORE SHOCKING,
ALONG COMES ADAM LANZA, WHO
STARTED HIS DAY WITH SHOOTING
HIS MOTHER.
AND FINISHED BY STORMING THAT
SCHOOL, WHERE OF ALL
THE PEOPLE HE SHOT, ONLY ONE
SURVIVED.
9:40 A.M.
REPORTS OF GUNFIRE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
>> SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
CALLER IS INDICATING THAT SHE
THINKS THERE'S SOMEONE SHOOTING
IN THE BUILDING.
>> Reporter: POLICE SAY
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA, SEEN
HERE AS A TEENAGER, WORE A
BULLETPROOF VEST AND WAS
CARRYING THREE SEMIAUTOMATIC
WEAPONS INCLUDING A RIFLE.
>> EVERYBODY WAS A LITTLE
SCARED, CRYING.
AND I FELT A LITTLE SICK.
>> Reporter: WITHIN FIVE TO TEN
MINUTES, THE FIRST S.W.A.T.
TEAMS ARRIVE.
>> I NEED UNITS IN THE SCHOOL.
I GOT BODIES HERE.
>> Reporter: OFFICERS HELPED
TEACHERS LEAD SEVERAL HUNDRED
STUDENTS TO A NEARBY
FIRESTATION.
>> WHEN THE POLICEMEN CAME IN TO
GET US, HE TOLD US TO CLOSE OUR
EYES.
AND LIKE ON THE PICTURE ON THE
NEWS, DO THIS.
>> Reporter: AT 10:30 A.M.,
PRESIDENT OBAMA WAS BRIEFED ON
THE SITUATION, WHILE POLICE
DISCOVERED A SECOND CRIME SCENE.
THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER, NANCY
LANZA, WHO AUTHORITIES BELIEVE
MAY HAVE VOLUNTEERED AT SANDY
HOOK AT ONE POINT, WAS SHOT
DEAD.
POLICE SAY ADAM LANZA SHOT HER
BEFORE HE STORMED THE SCHOOL.
AROUND NOON, ABC NEWS LEARNED
THAT LANZA HAD KILLED 27 PEOPLE,
MOST OF THEM CHILDREN, BEFORE
TURNING THE GUN ON HIMSELF.
SHORTLY AFTER 3:00, THE
PRESIDENT ADDRESSED THE NATION.
>> I KNOW THERE'S NOT A PARENT
IN AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL, LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
>> Reporter: BY 7:00 P.M., THIS
LITTLE TOWN HAD SETTLED INTO AN
ALL-TOO FAMILIAR POST-MASSACRE
ROUTINE, WITH PRAYER VIGILS.
>> MY GOD BLESS OUR CHILDREN WHO
ARE WITH US TODAY AND THOSE WHO
WERE TAKEN AWAY.
MAY GOD BLESS THE ADULTS WHO
LOST THEIR LIVES TODAY.
>> RIGHT NOW, WE ARE STANDING BY
FOR A POLICE PRESS CONFERENCE.
AND WHEN THAT HAPPENS, WE WILL
TAKE IT LIVE.
OVERNIGHT, POLICE ENGAGED IN THE
HORRIFYING WORK OF IDENTIFYING
THE YOUNG VICTIMS AND NOTIFYING
THEIR FAMILIES.
AS THEY CONTINUE TO CHASE THAT
BIG QUESTION, WHAT WAS HIS
MOTIVE?
WHY DID HE DO THIS?
IF PAST IS PROLOGUE, GEORGE, WE
MAY FIND OUT WHY HE LAUNCHED
THIS MASSACRE.
BUT THE ANSWER WILL BE DEEPLY
UNSATISFYING.
>> NO QUESTION ABOUT THAT.
BUT A LOT OF INVESTIGATION.
DAN, THANKS VERY MUCH.
ELIZABETH?
>> ALL RIGHT.
>>> PICKING UP WITH THOSE
INVESTIGATIONS, GEORGE.
NEW DETAILS ARE EMERGING THIS
MORNING ABOUT 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM
LANZA, WHO HAS BEEN IDENTIFIED
AS THE GUNMAN.
AUTHORITIES ARE NOW INTERVIEWING
HIS FAMILY AND HIS FRIENDS IN
THREE DIFFERENT STATES, TRYING
TO PIECE TOGETHER WHAT MAY HAVE
PUSHED HIM OVER THE EDGE.
ABC'S BRIAN ROSS JOINS ME IN THE
STUDIO WITH THE LATEST ON THAT
PART OF THE STORY.
GOOD MORNING, BRIAN.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING,
ELIZABETH.
HE WAS ARMED TO THE TEETH WITH
HIGH-POWERED WEAPONS, THAT
AUTHORITIES SAY WERE LEGALLY
OBTAINED BY SOMEONE IN HIS
FAMILY.
AND IN AN HOUR, ADAM LANZA WENT
FROM OBSCURITY TO INFAMY.
AUTHORITIES OVERNIGHT WERE
QUESTIONING FAMILY MEMBERS OF
THE 20-YEAR-OLD KILLER.
A MAN BELIEVED TO BE ADAM'S
OLDER BROTHER, RYAN, LEFT A NEW
JERSEY POLICE STATION, AS
AUTHORITIES SOUGHT TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT TURNED THE YOUNGEST MEMBER
OF THE LANZA FAMILY INTO A
MADMAN.
>> WE'LL GO BACKWARDS AS FAR AS
WE HAVE TO GO IN THIS
INVESTIGATION.
AND HOPEFULLY WE'LL STUMBLE ON
ANSWERS.
>> Reporter: FEDERAL AGENTS SAY
THEY RECOVERED TWO HIGH-POWERED
PISTOLS FROM THE SCENE, AND A
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE, CALLED A
BUSH MASTER, SIMILAR TO THIS
ONE.
BOTH ADAMS MOTHER AND FATHER
WERE LICENSED TO OWN SUCH
WEAPONS, ACCORDING TO FEDERAL
AGENTS.
>> THESE CRIMES INVOLVE PLANNING
AND THOUGHTFULNESS AND
STRATEGIZING, IN ORDER TO PUT
THE PLAN TOGETHER.
SO, WHAT MAY APPEAR TO BE SNAP
BEHAVIOR, IS NOT THAT AT ALL.
>> Reporter: EVEN BEFORE THE
SHOOTING, ADAM LANZA, SEEN HERE
IN A PHOTO TAKEN SEVEN YEARS
AGO, WAS KNOWN IN THE
NEIGHBORHOOD AS A TROUBLED
CHILD, WITH AN OVERBEARING
MOTHER.
>> MY SON PLAYED WITH HIM WHEN
THEY WERE YOUNG.
AND IN HER HOME, I KNOW SHE WAS
VERY PARTICULAR.
I JUST THINK SHE MAYBE HAD TOO
HIGH OF STANDARDS OR SOMETHING.
>> Reporter: ADAM'S FIRST VICTIM
WAS HIS MOTHER, NANCY, KILLED AT
THE FAMILY HOME, ACCORDING TO
POLICE.
ONLY THEN DID HE HEAD ACROSS
TOWN TO THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
WHERE AUTHORITIES SAID HIS
MOTHER MAY HAVE ONCE SERVED AS A
VOLUNTEER OR A TEACHER'S AIDE.
>> THE CHILDREN DIDN'T HARM HIM.
BUT THEY WERE ASSOCIATED WITH
HIS MOTHER.
AND HIS MOTHER, I BELIEVE, MAY
BE REAL FOCUS OF ALL OF THIS.
>> Reporter: AUTHORITIES SAY
SHELL CASINGS RECOVERED AT THE
SCENE INDICATED HE USED A VERY
POWERFUL WEAPON AND AMMUNITION
223, IT'S CALLED, FAVORED AMONG
DEER HUNTERS BECAUSE IT DOES
MAXIMUM INTERNAL DAMAGE.
>> AND ALSO, THE BUSH MASTER,
THE RIFLE WE'RE TOLD HE WAS
FOUND WITH, A WEAPON COMMONLY
USED BY SOLDIERS
IN AFGHANISTAN AND IRAQ.
THAT GIVES YOU SOME INDICATION
OF THE FIREPOWER HE HAD.
BRIAN, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
WE'LL HEAR MORE ON THE
INVESTIGATION THAT GOES FORWARD.
>>> GEORGE, EARLIER, WITH STATE
POLICE ON HOW THE FAMILIES ARE
BEING NOTIFIED.
GEORGE?
>> THANKS, ELIZABETH.
I'M HERE WITH LIEUTENANT PAUL
VANCE OF THE STATE POLICE HERE
IN CONNECTICUT.
KEEPING PEOPLE INFORMED ALL
THROUGH THE DAY YESTERDAY.
WE LEARNED OVERNIGHT THAT YOU
WERE ABLE TO NOTIFY ALL OF THE
FAMILIES.
>> OUR DETECTIVES MADE IT A
PRIORITY TO, IN FACT, IDENTIFY
ALL OF THE DECEASED VICTIMS, THE
CHILDREN, AND THE ADULTS, WITHIN
THE FACILITY.
>> AND WHAT MORE HAVE YOU BEEN
ABLE TO LEARN ABOUT ADAM LANZA?
WHY AND HOW HE DID THIS?
>> THIS IS SOMETHING THAT'S
GOING TO TAKE A SIGNIFICANT
AMOUNT OF TIME.
FROM THE ONSET, WE HAD TEAMS,
LOOKING INTO THE BACKGROUND,
PEELING THE ONION BACK, SO TO
SPEAK.
WE HAVE MANY, MANY QUESTIONS WE
NEED TO ASK AND WE NEED TO
EXPLORE.
>> THREE GUNS FOUND ON-SITE?
>> WE HAVEN'T DISCUSSED THAT AS
OF YET.
IN EXCESS OF THREE GUNS.
>> MORE THAN THREE GUNS.
WE KNOW ALSO THAT THE GUNS MATCH
GUNS THAT HIS MOTHER MAY HAVE
HAD.
HAVE YOU BEEN ABLE TO PUT THAT
TOGETHER YET?
>> I DON'T HAVE THAT INFORMATION
SPECIFICALLY.
>> DO YOU KNOW IF THEY WERE
OBTAINED LEGALLY.
>> THAT IS SOMETHING WE WOULD
ALSO EXPLORE IN THE
INVESTIGATION.
>> HOW ABOUT HOW ADAM LANZA
ACTUALLY GOT INTO THE SCHOOL.
THERE WERE SOME REPORTS THAT THE
PRINCIPAL MAY HAVE BUZZED HIM
IN.
>> I THINK THAT'S SIGNIFICANTLY
PREMATURE.
WE DO HAVE A PRETTY GOOD IDEA
HOW ENTRANCE WAS OBTAINED.
WE HAVE AN ADULT WITNESS THAT
WAS WOUNDED THAT SURVIVED, WHO
WILL BE INVALUABLE TO US.
>> WHY THIS SCHOOL?
>> WE DO HAVE SOME BACKGROUND
INFORMATION, THAT THERE WAS A
CONNECTION TO THE SCHOOL.
THE SPECIFIC CONNECTION, I'D
RATHER NOT DIVULGE AND RATHER
NOT GET INTO RIGHT NOW.
THERE'S A LOT OF DISCUSSION OUT
THERE.
>> HIS MOM MAY HAVE BEEN A
TEACHER THERE AT SOME POINT?
>> FOR OUR PURPOSES, IT'S BETTER
WE EXPLORE THAT CONFIDENTLY FOR
A LITTLE WHILE LONGER.
>> I KNOW YOU'VE SPOKEN BOTH TO
HIS BROTHER AND HIS FATHER
OVERNIGHT.
WHAT WERE YOU ABLE TO LEARN FROM
THEM?
>> WE'VE BEEN WORKING WITH LAW
ENFORCEMENT AGENCIES FROM OTHER
STATES, WHO ARE WORKING WITH US
ON THIS CASE, TO ASSIST US.
AND THEY HAVE EXTRACTED AND
OBTAINED INFORMATION THAT WAS
BENEFICIAL TO OUR INVESTIGATION.
>> ANY INDICATION THAT HE HAD
THREATENED TO KILL BEFORE?
>> THERE IS NO INDICATION THAT
SURFACED IMMEDIATELY.
THERE'S NONE WHATSOEVER.
>> ARE YOU CONFIDENT, NOW, THAT
HE ACTED ABSOLUTELY ALONE?
>> YEAH.
>> LIEUTENANT VANCE, THANK YOU
FOR YOUR TIME THIS MORNING.
>>> AS WE JUST HEARD, THE NAMES
OF THE VICTIMS WILL BE RELEASED
LATER THIS MORNING, INCLUDING
ALL THOSE CHILDREN.
PRAYING FOR THEM LAST NIGHT,
HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE PACKED INTO
CHURCHES IN THIS COMMUNITY.
ABC'S AMY ROBACH HAS MORE ON
THOSE VICTIMS.
GOOD MORNING, AMY.
>> GEORGE, IT'S IMPOSSIBLE TO
IMAGINE THE HORRIFIC REALITY
THAT SO MANY FAMILIES ARE WAKING
UP TO THIS MORNING.
THAT WHAT HAPPENED HERE LESS
THAN 24 HOURS AGO, ACTUALLY
HAPPENED.
AND THIS MORNING, WE ARE
LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE TEACHERS
AND THE CHILDREN INSIDE THAT
SCHOOL WHO LOST THEIR LIVES.
DISTRAUGHT FAMILY AND FRIENDS
CAME TOGETHER TO MOURN, TO CRY
AND TO REMEMBER THE 27 LIVES
LOST HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> I'M SO SORRY.
>> Reporter: OVERNIGHT, WE
LEARNED THE NAMES OF THOSE WE
LOST, AMONG THEM, 47-YEAR-OLD
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG.
AN AWARD-WINNING PRINCIPAL.
AND 27-YEAR-OLD VICKI SOTO, A
FIRST GRADE TEACHER, WHOSE FIRST
INSTINCT WAS TO PROTECT HER
STUDENTS, THROWING HERSELF IN
THE LINE OF FIRE.
20 OF 27 VICTIMS WERE STUDENTS
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
20 CHILDREN.
AND NOW, 20 FAMILIES MOURN
PRECIOUS LIVES LOST TOO SOON.
>> THIS SCARING EVENT, WILL BE
WITH US AND THEM FOR YEARS AND
YEARS TO COME.
>> Reporter: AND ACROSS THE
COUNTRY, AMERICA MOURNS.
AS PARENTS TRY TO EXPLAIN HOW A
NIGHTMARE BECAME A REALITY.
ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE TO EXPLAIN.
EXPERTS SAY THAT YOUR CHILDREN
DON'T HAVE TO HAVE BEEN HERE AT
THE SCENE TO BE TRAUMATIZED.
JUST HEARING AND LISTENING TO
WHAT HAPPENED HERE IN
CONNECTICUT IS TRAUMATIC IN AND
OF ITSELF.
IF YOU HAVE LITTLE ONES, SHIELD
THEM FROM THIS COVERAGE.
AND YOUR OLDER ONES, YOU WANT TO
TALK TO THEM AND LET THEM
EXPRESS THEMSELVES.
GEORGE?
>> AMY, THANKS.
>>> I'M HERE, NOW, WITH JAMES
WILTSIE, THE COUSIN OF ANOTHER
VICTIM AND A HERO, VICKI SOTO, A
TEACHER AT THE SCHOOL.
I'M SO SORRY FOR YOUR LOSS.
YOUR COUSIN, FROM WHAT WE KNOW,
DID EVERYTHING SHE COULD TO SAVE
THE LIVES OF SOME KIDS.
>> YES.
FROM WHAT WE'VE BEEN TOLD, MY
COUSIN, VICKI, AND HER FIRST
GRADE CLASSROOM, TOOK HER
STUDENTS AND HUDDLED THEM INTO A
CLOSET.
AND THEN, SHIELDED THE CHILDREN
IN THE CLOSET, TRYING TO PROTECT
THEM FROM BULLETS.
>> PUT HERSELF BETWEEN THE
GUNMAN AND THE KIDS.
>> YES.
SHE'S DEFINITELY A HERO.
HER LIFE DREAM WAS TO BE A
TEACHER.
AND HER INSTINCTS KICKED IN.
AND PROTECTED HER CHILDREN FROM
THE HARM THAT WAS COMING.
I'M SURE SHE HEARD WHAT WAS
GOING ON.
AND WENT INTO LOCKDOWN MODE.
TOOK HER KIDS, PUT THEM IN THE
CLOSET.
AND BY DOING SO, SHE LOST HER
LIFE PROTECTING THOSE LITTLE
ONES.
>> WHAT ELSE HAVE YOU BEEN ABLE
TO LEARN FROM THE POLICE OR
OTHERS ON THE SCENE?
>> JUST THAT SHE WAS A HERO.
THE WAY THAT SHE WAS FOUND,
HUDDLED OVER HER CHILDREN.
HER STUDENTS PROTECTING THEM.
YOU KNOW, DOING INSTINCTIVELY
WHAT SHE KNEW WOULD BE THE RIGHT
THING TO DO.
>>> GOOD MORNING.
WE HAVE BREAKING NEWS.
WE'RE GOING TO PAUSE FOR AN ABC
NEWS SPECIAL REPORT.
FOR THOSE OF YOU JOINING IN, WE
HAVE A SHOOTING AT THE NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, IN WHICH 27
PEOPLE WERE KILLED, 20 OF THEM
CHILDREN.
WE'RE ABOUT TO HAVE A NEWS
CONFERENCE OUTSIDE THE FIREHOUSE
WHERE ALL THIS HAS BEEN TAKING
PLACE.
SPEAKING TO REPORTERS, WE'LL
HAVE LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE OF
THE STATE POLICE, AS WELL AS
GEORGE SINCO, FROM THE NEWTOWN
COUNCIL.
ADAM LANZA AND THE SHOOTER'S
MOTHER, WHO APPEARS TO HAVE BEEN
THE MOTIVE FOR SPARKING THIS
DEADLY RAMPAGE.
ONCE THEY GO TO THE BANK OF
MICROPHONES, WE'LL TAKE THEM.
THIS HAS BEEN DEVASTATING NEWS
TO PROCESS.
A SMALL COMMUNITY INSIDE
CONNECTICUT.
THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HAD JUST
STARTED SCHOOL.
IT WAS SHORTLY AFTER 9:30 IN THE
MORNING, WHEN THE GUNMAN ENTERED
THE SCHOOL.
A LOT OF QUESTIONS HOW ADAM
LANZA GAINED ENTRY, WHETHER
SOMEONE BUZZED IN TO LET HIM IN.
HE CAME IN, WE'RE TOLD, WITH AT
LEAST THREE WEAPONS.
USED THOSE WEAPONS TO OPEN FIRE
ON TWO DIFFERENT CLASSROOMS IN
WHICH TEACHERS AND CHILDRENS
WERE KILLED.
LET'S LISTEN IN.
>> WANT TO BRING YOU UP TO DATE
WITH THE PROGRESS THAT WE'VE
MADE IN THIS INVESTIGATION.
WITH ME IS THE CHIEF OF POLICE
OF NEWTOWN.
AS YOU KNOW, THE VICTIMS HAVE
BEEN POSITIVELY IDENTIFIED BY
THE OFFICE OF THE CHIEF STATE'S
MEDICAL EXAMINER.
THEY'RE STILL IN THE PROCESS OF
DOING SOME OF THEIR WORK.
AS SOON AS THAT WORK IS
COMPLETED, WE WILL BE PREPARED
TO RELEASE, IN WRITING, TO YOU,
A FORMAL LIST OF NAMES,
BIRTHDAYS AND INFORMATION.
THERE'S ONE, A COUPLE MAJOR
FACTORS, NUMBER ONE.
WHEN WE RELEASE THAT LIST, AND
WE WOULD ASK YOU AGAIN, AS WE
DID YESTERDAY, AT THE REQUEST OF
ALL THE FAMILY MEMBERS, THEY
HAVE ASKED FOR YOU TO PLEASE
RESPECT THEIR PRIVACY.
THEY ARE GOING THROUGH, AS I
KNOW YOU UNDERSTAND, A VERY
DIFFICULT AND TRYING TIME WE
HAVE, IN FACT, THE OFFICERS OF
THE CHIEF AND THE COLONEL,
REASSIGN, WE CONTINUE TO ASSIGN
A TROOPER TO THESE FOLKS TO HELP
TO MAINTAIN THAT SOLITUDE.
SO, AGAIN, I WOULD ASK YOU, AND
I'M PLEADING WITH YOU, AS YOU
KNOW THIS IS EXTREMELY
HEARTBREAKING, DIFFICULT THING
FOR THESE FOLKS TO ENDURE, TO
PLEASE ABIDE BY THEIR REQUEST.
IN ADDITION, FOR THE
TOWNSPEOPLE, IN THE TOWN OF
NEWTOWN, A CRISIS INTERVENTION
TEAM, FROM YALE NEW HAVEN
HOSPITAL HAS BEEN ESTABLISHED
HERE IN THE COMMUNITY.
AND THEY CAN BE REACHED BY
TELEPHONE.
THE TELEPHONE NUMBER IS
203-270-4283.
THEY'RE OPEN AND THEY'RE
AVAILABLE TO ANYONE IN THE
COMMUNITY WHO MAY HAVE THE NEED
TO DISCUSS, TO TALK, TO TALK
ABOUT THIS INCIDENT IN ITS
ENTIRETY.
I HAVE THE ABILITY TO TAKE SOME
QUESTIONS.
I JUST SIMPLY WANT YOU TO
UNDERSTAND THAT WE STILL HAVE
MAJOR CRIME DETECTIVES AND
NEWTOWN DETECTIVES WORKING AT
THE SCENE IN THE SCHOOL.
THAT IS NOT COMPLETED.
THAT PROBABLY WILL NOT BE
COMPLETED FOR AT LEAST ANOTHER
DAY AND A HALF TO TWO DAYS.
AND I'M PUTTING A TIME LIMIT ON
IT.
IT COULD TAKE LONGER.
AS I EXPLAINED TO YOU IN
PREVIOUS PRESS CONFERENCES WE'VE
DONE, EVERYTHING WE NEED TO DO
TO LITERALLY PEEL BACK THE
ONION, LAYER BY LAYER, AND
EXAMINE EVERY CRACK AND CREVASSE
OF THAT FACILITY.
AND THAT DOES NOT INCLUDE OR
EXCLUDE THE OUTSIDE OF THE
BUILDING.
THE OUTSIDE OF THE BUILDING IS
ALSO PART OF THE CRIME SCENE.
EVERY VEHICLE IN THAT LOT.
IT'S GOING TO BE A LONG,
PAINSTAKING PROCESS.
WE HAVE THREE TEAMS, NOW.
THREE, MAJOR CRIME TEAMS IN THE
COMMUNITY.
OUR LOCAL PARTNERS ARE WORKING
WITH US.
WE'RE GOING TO EXPEDITE THAT
ALONG AS QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE.
WE HAD A MEETING THIS MORNING.
THAT WAS WITH SUPERINTENDENT OF
SCHOOLS.
SHE WILL BE, HOPEFULLY, IN THE
NOT TOO DISTANT FUTURE UP HERE
TO TALK BRIEFLY ABOUT SOME OF
THE ISSUES THAT SHE HAS
ENCOUNTERED.
THE MINUTE THE MEDICAL EXAMINER
IS DONE, AND I MEAN THAT
SINCERELY, THE MINUTE HE IS
DONE, HE IS COMING HERE.
AND WE WILL, AGAIN, PROVIDE ALL
THE DETAILED INFORMATION OR AS
MUCH DETAILED INFORMATION AS WE
CAN, RELATIVE TO THE WORK THAT
HIS OFFICE DID, BOTH OVERNIGHT
AND CONTINUED TO DO AS WE SPEAK.
AS FAR AS ACTUAL, SPECIFIC
QUESTIONS, I HAVE TO TELL YOU,
THERE'S CERTAIN THINGS WE'RE
HOLDING CLOSE TO OUR CHEST IN
THIS INVESTIGATION.
SO NOTHING IS TAKEN OUT OF
CONTEXT.
>> THERE ARE REPORTS THAT THERE
WERE OTHER GUNS FOUND IN THE
SCHOOL.
>> THAT'S NOT ACCURATE.
THE WEAPONRY THAT -- WASN'T
RECOVERED BY OUR INVESTIGATORS,
RECOVERED IN CLOSE PROXIMITY OF
THE DECEASED.
WE'RE INVESTIGATING THE HISTORY
OF EACH AND EVERY WEAPON.
WE WILL KNOW EVERY, SINGLE THING
ABOUT THOSE WEAPONS.
I DON'T FOLLOW QUESTIONS ABOUT
WHO ARE THE OWNERS AND SO FORTH.
THAT'S ALL BEING DONE BY THE
INVESTIGATORS ASSIGNED TO THAT
TASK.
WE ARE, AGAIN, WE'RE GOING TO
ALLOW THE MEDICAL EXAMINER.
GOING TO WAIT FOR THE MEDICAL
EXAMINER TO PROVIDE THE
IDENTITIES OF THE SHOOTER, OF
ALL THE DECEASED IN THIS
INVESTIGATION.
>> THERE WERE ANY WRITINGS, ANY
E-MAILS, ANY MESSAGES, THAT
WOULD GIVE LIGHT TO A MOTIVE?
>> THAT'S A FAIR, GOOD QUESTION.
THE ANSWER I CAN GIVE YOU ON
THAT IS, OUR INVESTIGATORS AT
THE CRIME SCENE, THE SCHOOL, AND
SECONDARILY AT THE SECONDARY
CRIME SCENE WHERE THE FEMALE IS
DECEASED, DID PRODUCE SOME VERY
GOOD EVIDENCE IN THIS
INVESTIGATION, THAT OUR
INVESTIGATORS WILL BE ABLE TO
USE AND HOPEFULLY PAINTING A
COMPLETE PICTURE AS TO HOW AND
MORE IMPORTANTLY WHY THIS
OCCURRED.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO NAME THE
EVIDENCE.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO TALK ABOUT
THE EVIDENCE.
IT'S SIMPLY STATED AS PART AND
PARCEL OF THE INVESTIGATION.
I DON'T WANT TO TAKE IT OUT OF
CONTEXT OF WHAT'S BEING DONE.
WE HAVE ESTABLISHED A POINT OF
ENTRY.
I CAN TELL YOU IT WAS BELIEVED
HE WAS NOT VOLUNTARILY LET INTO
THE SCHOOL AT ALL.
THAT HE FORCED HIS WAY INTO THE
SCHOOL.
BUT THAT'S AS FAR AS WE CAN GO
ON THAT.
ARE THERE WHAT?
YEAH.
QUITE FRANKLY, THAT'S SOMETHING,
AGAIN, IF YOU TAKE IT OUT OF
CONTEXT, IT SOUNDS SUSPICIOUS.
BUT AS THE RESCUE CREWS ARRIVE,
THE ACTIVE SHOOTING TEAMS
ENTERED THE SCHOOL, THEY ENTERED
THE SCHOOL FROM SEVERAL
DIFFERENT POINTS AND IT
NECESSITATED FORCING THEIR WAY
TO GAIN ACCESS AND RESCUE AS
MANY STUDENTS AND FACULTY AS
THEY COULD.
HENCE, LAW ENFORCEMENT BROKE
MANY WINDOWS.
WHAT'S THAT?
THE OTHER CRIME SCENE?
YEAH, THE SECONDARY CRIME SCENE,
AS I TOLD YOU, WAS A CRIME
SCENE, DISCOVERED PURSUANT TO
THE INVESTIGATION.
ONCE WE HAD A POSITIVE IDENTI
IDENTIFICATION ON THE SUSPECT,
WE DID A GREAT DEAL OF WORK,
INCLUDING AND NOT LIMITED TO,
RELATIVES, FRIENDS, CO-WORKERS,
FORMER STUDENTS, LOCATION OF
RESIDENCE.
AND ALL THOSE AREAS HAD TO BE --
PEOPLE HAD TO BE INTERVIEWED.
AND ALL THOSE AREAS HAD TO BE
EXAMINED.
HENCE, THAT CAUSED US TO
DISCOVER THE SECONDARY CRIME
SCENE, WHICH WAS A SOLE
RESIDENCE WITH THE DECEASED.
THE DETECTIVES WILL CERTAINLY
ANALYZE EVERYTHING AND PUT A
COMPLETE PICTURE TOGETHER OF THE
EVIDENCE THAT THEY DID OBTAIN.
AND WE'RE HOPEFUL, WE'RE HOPEFUL
THAT IT WILL PAINT A COMPLETE
PICTURE OF HOW THIS ENTIRE
INCIDENT, UNFORTUNATE INCIDENT,
OCCURRED.
I'M SORRY?
SHE IS DOING FINE.
SHE HAS BEEN TREATED.
AND SHE'LL BE INSTRUMENT IN THIS
INVESTIGATION.
I'M SURE YOU CAN UNDERSTAND.
THAT, I DON'T KNOW.
FORCED HIS WAY INTO THE SCHOOL.
THAT WOULD BE ACCURATE ACCORDING
TO INVESTIGATORS.
YES.
I DON'T WANT TO BE TOO SPECIFIC
BECAUSE, QUITE FRANKLY, I DON'T
KNOW.
I WOULD SIMPLY -- I'VE BEEN
INFORMED THAT IT WAS FORCIBLY
ENTERED AND WAS NOT ALLOWED TO
ENTER, IF YOU WILL.
WHAT I'D LIKE TO DO IS I'D LIKE
TO GET THE NEXT PORTION, IF YOU
WILL, OF TODAY.
I DON'T WANT TO KEEP YOU HERE
ALL DAY.
I WANT TO DO THIS AS
EXPEDITIOUSLY AS I CAN.
WE WANT TO GET THE
SUPERINTENDENT, WANTS TO COME UP
WITH THE TOWN LEADERS, TO
DISCUSS CERTAIN AREAS OF HER
RESPONSIBILITY.
AND THEN, WE CERTAINLY WANT TO
GET THE MEDICAL EXAMINER UP
HERE.
AGAIN, WE'LL DO THAT AS QUICKLY
AS WE POSSIBLY CAN TO GET THE
LIST OF THE I.D.s AND ALL OF THE
INFORMATION OUT TO YOU.
FOR ANY OF YOU THAT ARE NEW HERE
TODAY, THE LIEUTENANT AND I PUT
TOGETHER A WRITTEN PRESS
RELEASE.
WE'LL PROVIDE THOSE TO YOU AT MY
VEHICLE.
PLEASE, DON'T RUSH MY VEHICLE.
WE SHOULD HAVE ENOUGH FOR
EVERYONE.
IF NOT, WE'LL BRING MORE THE
NEXT TIME WE COME OUT.
AND IT LAYS OUT THE BASIC
DETAILS OF EVERYTHING, LEADING
UP UNTIL TODAY.
ALL RIGHT?
WE WILL TRY -- I DON'T WANT TO
GIVE YOU A TIME.
WE'LL TRY TO BE BACK HERE, I'LL
SAY WITHIN THE HOUR.
I'LL MAKE NOTIFICATION TO SOME
OF YOU THAT I CAN THAT WE'RE ON
THE WAY.
>> DID THE MOTHER HAVE ANY
CONNECTIONS TO THE SCHOOL?
>> YOU HAVE TO UNDERSTAND THAT
AFTER THE SHOOTING, WE DID A
COMPLETE AND THOROUGH SEARCH OF
THE AREA, THE ENTIRE
NEIGHBORHOOD, WITH OUR LOCAL
PARTNERS.
EVERYTHING WAS EXAMINED.
IF WE FOUND ANYONE THAT WAS IN
THE WOODS, CUTTING WOOD, THAT
WOULD BE DETAINED, PENDING THE
INVESTIGATION.
THERE WERE NO OTHER ARRESTS THAT
WERE ASSOCIATED WITH THIS
INVESTIGATION THAT OCCURRED.
>> WHAT ABOUT THE MINDSET OF --
>> I WOULD HAVE YOU ADDRESS THAT
WITH THE SUPERINTENDENT OF
SCHOOLS.
OKAY?
SHE CAN GIVE YOU THAT ANSWER.
WE WILL BE BACK.
I NEED TO GET -- IF I DON'T GET
HERE, WE'RE GOING TO BE HERE
QUITE SOME TIME.
I KNOW YOU HAVE A LOT OF
QUESTIONS.
AND I THINK THE PEOPLE THAT ARE
COMING HERE, THAT WE'RE BRINGING
HERE TO SPEAK TO YOU, CAN ANSWER
THESE QUESTIONS AND TAKE A LOT
OF THE MYSTERY OUT OF WHAT WE'VE
BEEN DEALING WITH FOR THE LAST
24 HOURS.
OKAY?
WE WILL BE BACK.
>> AND LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE
FROM CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE,
WRAPPING UP HIS PRESS
CONFERENCE.
SOME NEWS EMERGING THERE.
FIRST OF ALL, THEY HAVE
POSITIVELY IDENTIFIED ALL OF THE
VICTIMS.
REMEMBER, 20 OF THEM, YOUNG
CHILDREN, ALTHOUGH THEY'RE
RELEASING THE LIST OF THOSE
NAMES, WHICH I'M SURE LOOKS LIKE
A KINDERGARTNER OR FIRST GRADE
CLASS LIST, WITH THE NAMES AND
AGES OF BIRTH.
PLEADING WITH THE MEDIA TO GIVE
THOSE FAMILIES PRIVACY.
THOSE FAMILIES GRIEVING AN
UNIMAGINABLE LOSS AT THIS POINT.
A HOTLINE NUMBER TO ANYBODY
NEEDING THERAPY, COUNSELING OVER
THE PHONE.
ALSO, THIS IS KEY.
ALL OF THE WEAPONS WERE
APPARENTLY FOUND INSIDE THE
SCHOOL NEAR THE BODY OF THE
SHOOTER.
AT LEAST THREE WEAPONS.
THERE'S BEEN GOOD EVIDENCE FOR A
MOTIVE FOR THE SHOOTING THAT WAS
FOUND AT THE VICTIM'S HOME THAT
HE APPARENTLY SHARED WITH HIS
MOTHER, WHERE HE HAS APPARENTLY,
BEFORE GOING TO THE SCHOOL AND
OPENING FIRE ON ALL THOSE
CHILDREN, KILLED HIS MOTHER BY
FIRING ON HER AT POINT-BLANK
RANGE.
ALSO, EVIDENCE THAT HE FORCED
HIS WAY INTO THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AFTER SPECULATION THAT,
PERHAPS, HE HAD BEEN BUZZED IN.
AND THAT FINALLY, THE SOLE
SURVIVOR IN THE SHOOTING, ONE
PERSON SURVIVED, THAT SHOOTING.
WILL BE CRUCIAL TO THE
INVESTIGATION GOING FORWARD.
SHE IS DOING FINE.
OBVIOUSLY, WILL HAVE VALUABLE
EVIDENCE FOR POLICE GOING
FORWARD.
I'M ELIZABETH VARGAS IN
NEW YORK.
WE'LL HAVE ALL THE LATEST,
CONTINUING THROUGHOUT THE DAY,
RIGHT HERE ON ABC NEWS.
AND STAY TUNED FOR THE LATEST ON
THIS TRAGEDY TO "WORLD NEWS"
WITH DAVID MUIR.
>>> IT SHOULD NEVER HAVE
HAPPENED TO OUR CHILDREN.
THEY WERE VERY LITTLE.
>> SUCH A SAD SATURDAY MORNING
HERE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
YOU SEE THE PAIN THERE.
YOU SEE THE GRIEF.
MOTHERS AND FATHERS MOURNING
THEIR CHILDREN THIS MORNING.
20 CHILDREN DEAD.
THE WORST SHOOTING EVER AT A
GRADE SCHOOL HERE IN THE UNITED
STATES.
THE GUNMAN, ADAM LANZA, WAS 20
YEARS OLD.
HE SHOT HIS MOTHER BEFORE COMING
TO THE SCHOOL TO SHOOT SO MANY
CHILDREN, ADULTS, AS WELL.
AS I SAID, THE DEADLIEST GRADE
SCHOOL SHOOTING EVER IN OUR
HISTORY.
AND, ELIZABETH, SO MANY PEOPLE
HERE HAVING SUCH A HARD TIME
COMING TO GRIPS WITH THIS PAIN.
>> IT'S UNIMAGINABLE, GEORGE.
I THINK EVERY PARENT WHEN THEY
HEARD THIS STORY BREAK, JUST WAS
IN SHOCK.
I FELT, I KNOW, PHYSICALLY SICK
TO MY STOMACH.
A LOT OF OTHER PEOPLE FELT THE
SAME WAY.
AND COMING UP IN THIS HALF HOUR,
WE'RE GOING TO WEIGH IN WITH
EXPERTS ON HOW TO TALK TO OUR
KIDS ABOUT THIS TRAGEDY, ABOUT
THE SHOOTINGS.
THEY WILL, OF COURSE, HEAR ABOUT
THAT.
IT VARIES WITH THE AGE.
IT VARIES WITH THE CHILD.
BUT THE EXPERTS HAVE GREAT
ADVICE.
IT'S ALL IMPORTANT THAT WE MAKE
OUR KIDS FEEL SAFE, EVEN AS THEY
LEARN ABOUT THIS HORRIFIC
MASSACRE, IN NEWTOWN, WHERE
YOU'RE STANDING, GEORGE.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
IT'S SO HARD TO FIGURE OUT HOW
TO GIVE THEM WHAT THEY NEED TO
KNOW.
I'M HERE WITH DAN HARRIS, WHO
HAS BEEN HERE FROM THE VERY
BEGINNING.
WE'RE GOING TO LEARN ALL OF THE
IDENTITIES OF THE VICTIMS THIS
MORNING.
>> WE'RE EXPECTING THAT THIS
MORNING IN A PRESS CONFERENCE
COMING UP.
HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW AT THIS
POINT.
WE'RE SEEING A MASSIVE
INVESTIGATION UNFOLD.
AT THE HEART OF THIS POLICE
INVESTIGATION RIGHT NOW IS THIS
QUESTION.
WHY?
WHAT WAS THE MOTIVE OF THE
SUSPECT, 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA?
WE KNOW HIS RAMPAGE BEGAN WITH
THE MURDER OF HIS MOTHER HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
HE THEN STORMED THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WHERE HE
KILLED 20 CHILDREN, MANY OF THEM
FIRST GRADERS AND SIX ADULTS.
POLICE SAY HIS MOM HAD SOME SORT
OF CONNECTION TO THE SCHOOL.
BUT IT'S UNCLEAR WHAT.
SHE MAY HAVE WORKED THERE AT
SOME POINT.
POLICE TELL US THEY'VE BEEN
INTERVIEWING PEOPLE WHO KNOW
LANZA, IN THREE STATE, INCLUDING
HIS FATHER AND OLDER BROTHER.
WE KNOW HE USED AT LEAST THREE
WEAPONS.
THREE OF THEM SEMIAUTOMATIC.
ONE OF THEM A RIFLE.
OVERNIGHT, POLICE IDENTIFIED THE
BODIES AND WENT THROUGH THE
HORRIFYING TASK OF NOTIFYING THE
PARENTS.
THIS MORNING, THEY'LL BE
RELEASING PUBLICLY THE NAMES OF
THE DEAD AS THIS TOWN GRIEVES
AND THE ENTIRE COUNTRY GRIEVES
WITH THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN.
GEORGE?
>> THE FAMILIES, ONLY LEARNED
EARLY THIS MORNING, FOR SURE,
WHAT HAPPENED.
WE GO TO ABC'S JIM AVILA NOW.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING,
GEORGE.
WE'RE STANDING IN FRONT OF, NEXT
TO THE HOME, WHERE APPARENTLY
THIS KILLING SPREE BEGAN.
A TROUBLED SON, KILLING HIS
MOTHER.
A WOMAN THAT RELATIVES SAY, WAS
A MOM WHO WOULD HAVE DONE
ANYTHING TO HELP HER SON IF SHE
KNEW HE NEEDED HELP.
AS NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, IS
STILL TRYING TO MAKE SENSE OF
THIS INEXPLICABLE SHOOTING, NEW
DETAILS ARE EMERGING ON THE
LANZA FAMILY.
>> I REMEMBER THEM TO BE SHY,
QUIET, WELL-BEHAVED KIDS.
>> Reporter: 24-YEAR-OLD RYAN
LANZA, BROTHER OF SUSPECTED
GUNMAN, ADAM, WAS TAKEN INTO
CUSTODY AND QUESTIONED BY
AUTHORITIES.
BUT POLICE SAY HE IS NOT
SUSPECTED OF BEING INVOLVED IN
THE SHOOTING.
RYAN IS A GRADUATE OF QUINNIPIAC
UNIVERSITY AND WORKED AT ERNST &
YOUNG IN MANHATTAN.
INVESTIGATORS ARE LOOKING AT
WHETHER THE 20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER
WAS CARRYING RYAN'S I.D. AT THE
CAUSE OF THE SHOOTING, CAUSING
THE INITIAL MISIDENTIFICATION.
AUTHORITIES TOLD ABC NEWS, THEIR
MOTHER, NANCY LANZA, WAS FOUND
FATALLY SHOT IN HER CONNECTICUT
HOME.
>> SHE RAISED VERY NICE BOYS, TO
ME.
THAT'S WHY I THINK IT'S A SHOCK
TO EVEN KNOW THEM AND REALIZE
WHO THEY ARE.
AND WHAT HE DID.
>> Reporter: STATE RECORDS
INDICATE SHE WAS DIVORCED FROM
HER HUSBAND IN 2009.
BOTH NANCY AND HER EX-HUSBAND,
PETER LANZA, WERE REQUIRED TO
COMPLETE A PARENTING EDUCATION
PROGRAM, NECESSARY FOR DIVORCED
COUPLES WITH CHILDREN UNDER 18.
>> I THINK THE FACT THAT THE
PARENTS WERE DIVORCED MUST HAVE
CONTRIBUTED TO IT.
>> Reporter: THE SHOOTER'S
FATHER, PETER LANZA, IS A VICE
PRESIDENT AT G.E. CAPITAL, AND
HAD BEEN A PARTNER AT ERNST &
YOUNG, WHERE HIS SON, RYAN,
WORKS NOW.
HE IS NOW REMARRIED AND WAS
QUESTIONED BY AUTHORITIES.
BUT IS NOT UNDER ANY SUSPICION.
THE MOTHER WHO LIVED HERE ON
THIS STREET, WAS -- HAD SOME
CONNECTION TO THE SCHOOL, WE'RE
TOLD.
BUT THE SUPERINTENDENT SAID,
THIS MORNING, THAT SHE WAS NOT
OFFICIALLY EMPLOYED THERE.
SHE MAY HAVE VOLUNTEERED IN SOME
WAY.
AS FOR THE FATHER, THEY'RE
DIVORCED.
HE DOESN'T LIVE HERE.
HE LIVES IN STANFORD.
AND HE APPARENTLY FOUND OUT
ABOUT THE KILLING FROM A
REPORTER WHO WAS IN HIS DRIVEWAY
WHEN HE CAME HOME AND INFORMED
HIM.
ELIZABETH?
>> ALL RIGHT, JIM.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>>> THE QUESTION GOES TO WHAT
WOULD MAKE A PERSON DO SOMETHING
LIKE THIS?
SOMETHING SO TERRIFIC TO
CHILDREN SO LITTLE.
LET'S BRING IN PSYCHIATRIST
DR. JANET TAYLOR TO TALK ABOUT
THE MIND OF THE SHOOTER.
CLEARLY, EVERYBODY UNDERSTANDS
THIS YOUNG MAN WAS MENTALLY ILL.
BUT TO PICK CHILDREN, YOUNG,
YOUNG CHILDREN, AS HIS VICTIMS.
I MEAN, THAT IS ABOUT THE WORST
THING YOU COULD DO.
WHAT DOES THAT TELL YOU ABOUT
HIS MOTIVATION?
ABOUT HIS STABILITY OR
INSTABILITY, OBVIOUSLY?
>> CERTAINLY, THERE IS AN EVIL
JUST HEINOUS QUALITY TO IT.
AND THE FACT IS, IT'S IMPOSSIBLE
TO PREDICT WHO WILL BE VIOLENT.
BUT RISK FACTORS ARE,
INDIVIDUALS WHO HAVE BEEN
EXPOSED TO PHYSICAL ABUSE,
SEXUAL ABUSE.
IF THERE'S AN UNDERLYING
PSYCHOLOGICAL IMPAIRMENT, WHICH
CERTAINLY HE WAS DESCRIBED AS
ODD AND POSSIBLY IN THE AUTISM
SPECTRUM.
IF THEY HAVE ACCESS TO GUNS AND
WEAPONS.
AND CERTAINLY, INDIVIDUALS WHO
MAY HAVE REVENGE IN THEIR MIND.
BUT AGAIN, WHO WANTS TO HURT
INNOCENT CHILDREN?
>> OBVIOUSLY, THERE'S A LOT OF
PEOPLE IN THIS COUNTRY THAT ARE
AUTISTIC OR HAVE ASPERGER'S
SYNDROME AND NEVER COMMIT ANY
VIOLENT ACT.
A LOT OF PEOPLE WHO, FRANKLY,
ARE MENTALLY ILL.
A QUARTER OF THE POPULATION, BY
SOME ESTIMATES, ARE MENTALLY ILL
AND NEVER COMMIT A VIOLENT ACT.
THIS YOUNG MAN, ACCORDING TO
POLICE, IS SHOOTING HIS MOTHER
AT HIS HOME, AND GETTING IN THE
CAR WITH HIS WEAPONS, DRIVING TO
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, WALKING IN
AND SHOOTING KINDERGARTNERS AND
FIRST GRADERS.
>> I THINK THE PREMEDITATIVE
QUALITY OF IT CERTAINLY
INDICATES A FACT THAT YOU CAN BE
MENTALLY ILL.
YOU CAN BE PSYCHOTIC AND KNOW
RIGHT FROM AMONG.
AND THIS CASE, I THINK HE
DELIBERATELY KNEW WHAT HE WAS
DOING.
CERTAINLY, HIS UNDERLYING MENTAL
ILLNESS, PRESUMABLY THAT HE HAD,
WAS NOT AN EXCUSE IN ANY WAY FOR
A WHAT HE DID.
>> OBVIOUSLY, THE FACT THAT THE
TARGET WAS YOUNG CHILDREN.
DOES THAT GIVE YOU ANY
INDICATION OF PERHAPS HE WAS
TRYING TO HURT SOMETHING THAT
MEANT SOMETHING TO HIS MOTHER?
>> I MEAN, PRESUMABLY THAT WOULD
BE THE LINK.
UNFORTUNATELY, WE WILL NOT KNOW.
BUT YOU HAVE TO THINK THAT THE
FACT HE KILLED HIS MOTHER AND
THEN WENT AND KILLED INNOCENT
CHILDREN, MAYBE THERE'S A LINK
BETWEEN HIS MOTHER AND THE KIDS.
OR MAYBE HE JUST FELT LIKE HE
WAS DOING SOMETHING SO HORRIFIC
THAT HE WOULD ALWAYS BE
REMEMBERED.
WE WON'T KNOW.
AT THE END OF THE DAY, WE HAVE
TO PRAY FOR THE FAMILIES AND
UNDERSTAND THAT AT SOME POINT,
WE WILL UNDERSTAND THE MOTIVE.
BUT IT STILL WILL NEVER BE
ENOUGH TO BRING THE POOR KIDS
AND ADULTS WHO DIED BACK.
>> THE FOCUS IS ON THE FAMILIES
AND THE VICTIMS.
DR. TAYLOR, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>>> LET'S CHECK IN FOR THE
WEATHER AND GINGER ZEE THIS
MORNING.
GOOD MORNING, GINGER.
>> GOOD MORNING, ELIZABETH.
AND GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE.
THERE WERE THREE REPORTED
TORNADOES IN NORTH TEXAS AND
WIND DAMAGE, TOO.
THOSE STORMS ARE GOING TO
EVENTUALLY MOVE EAST.
BUT IT'S NOT GOING TO BE AS
STRONG TODAY.
SO, IF YOU'RE IN THIS AREA FROM
MEMPHIS, TO JACKSON, NEW
ORLEANS, INCLUDED THERE, YOU MAY
HAVE SOME GUSTY WINDS, SMALL
HAIL.
BUT IT'S NOT GOING TO BE AS
POWERFUL AS YESTERDAY.
REAL QUICKLY, CASCADE MOUNTAIN
SNOW.
8 TO 14 INCHES UP THERE IN PARTS
OF THE PACIFIC NORTHWEST WITH
THAT STORM.
>> THANK YOU, GINGER.
>>> WHEN WE COME BACK, HOW TO
TALK TO OUR CHILDREN ABOUT THIS
TRAGEDY.
MOND.
FOR OVER 90 YEARS...
WE HAVE CONTINUED
TO PERFECT THIS DIAMOND.
[ Female Announcer ]
NOW KAY JEWELERS BRINGS YOU
TOLKOWSKY IDEAL CUT DIAMONDS --
FROM THE FAMILY THAT INVENTED
THE IDEAL CUT.
AT KAY, THE NUMBER-ONE
JEWELRY STORE IN AMERICA.
FROM OUR FAMILY...
TO THE BEGINNING OF YOURS.
YES! YES!
♪ EVERY KISS BEGINS WITH KAY
He is a good little monkey
and always very curious.
One day George got an important
letter...
He's built a rocket ship to
travel into space.
It's just the right size for a
clever monkey.
Do you want to go into space,
George?
You will have to be very brave.
Hi, Grandma!
Oh hi,. my little monkey!
Here.
Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
Everyone got on and they were
off to the launching site.
Google, how far is Earth to the
Moon?
Moon is 238,900 miles...
The great moment had come...
...5...4...3...2...1
[ Male Announcer ]
WATCH OUT, CASANOVA.
THERE'S A NEW LADIES' MAN
IN TOWN,
AND HE KNOWS TO SHOP AT
Walgreens DURING THE HOLIDAYS.
WE HAVE GREAT GIFTS
AT GREAT PRICES,
ONLINE AND IN THE STORE.
SO YOU'RE SURE TO FIND
SOMETHING
FOR THAT SPECIAL SOMEONE --
EVEN IF YOU HAVE
SEVERAL SPECIAL SOMEONES.
SHOP Walgreens FOR GREAT GIFTS,
LIKE Lindt Lindor Truffles,
AND GET UP TO 10,000
Balance Rewards POINTS
ON YOUR TOTAL PURCHASE, HERE.
At THE Corner
OF Happy AND Healthy.
ON YOUR TOTAL PURCHASE, HERE.
OH MY GOD, HIM DANCE?
HE SHOULHAVE YOU SEEN HIS SHOES?
THEY LOOK LIKE,
THEY LOOK LIKE FLIPPERS.
[ aunts laughing ]
[ Male Announcer ]
FIND SOME PEACE THIS HOLIDAY.
GET AN 8 PIECE MEAL
NOW WITH A DOZEN
DELICIOUS COOKIES
BAKED IN-STORE.
THE KFC FESTIVE FEAST.
ALL FOR JUST $19.99.
YES YOU DID.
NO I DIDN'T.
DID NOT.
[ Male Announcer ]
TODAY TASTES SO GOOD.
>>> WE ARE BACK, NOW, FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE SEE THE PICTURES OF THE
GRIEVING PARENTS AND FAMILIES.
STRUCK BY THAT TRAGEDY AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AND ALL OF US PARENTS, LOOKING
FOR ADVICE ON HOW TO TALK TO OUR
CHILDREN ABOUT SOMETHING THAT'S
SO HARD TO COMPREHEND.
I'M JOINED BY OUR CHIEF HEALTH
AND MEDICAL EDITOR, DR. RICHARD
BESSER FOR THAT.
FIRST OF ALL, THE KIDS SO
DIRECTLY IMPACTIVE, THE CHILDREN
IN THAT SCHOOL AND THIS
COMMUNITY.
>> THOSE CHILDREN ARE REALLY
GOING TO NEED SPECIAL CARE TO
MAKE SURE THIS EVENT DOESN'T
DEFINE THEM FOR THE REST OF
THEIR LIVES.
UNLIKE OTHER YOUNG CHILDREN,
THEIR PARENTS ARE GOING TO NEED
TO TALK TO THEM CLEARLY ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
EXPLAIN IT.
EXPRESS THEIR FEELINGS.
YOU WANT TO MAKE SURE THE
CHILDREN DON'T BECOME TRAGEDY
CELEBRITIES.
THAT THIS IS ALL THEY'RE KNOWN
FOR.
AS SOON AS YOU GET THEM IN
NORMAL ROUTINES, TO PICKING UP
SOMETHING FUN TO DO.
LETTING THEM KNOW IT'S STILL
OKAY TO HAVE FUN, THAT'S
IMPORTANT.
BUT PROFESSIONAL GRIEF
COUNSELORS ARE GOING TO BE A BIG
PART OF WHAT THESE CHILDREN
EXPERIENCED.
>> HOW ABOUT CHILDREN MORE
GENERALLY?
I HAVE A 7-YEAR-OLD AND A
10-YEAR-OLD.
MY 7-YEAR-OLD DIDN'T KNOW ABOUT
IT.
DIDN'T WANT TO KNOW ABOUT IT.
MY 10-YEAR-OLD HAD QUESTIONS.
HOW DO YOU TALK TO THEM?
>> IT'S GREAT IF YOU CAN SHIELD
YOUR 7-YEAR-OLD.
FOR 10-YEAR-OLDS, YOU WANT TO
KNOW WHAT THEY'RE FEELING.
YOU WANT TO BE ABLE TO LISTEN TO
THEM.
THEY NEED TO SEE THAT YOU'RE SAD
BUT UNDER CONTROL.
IT'S OKAY TO BE ANGRY AND SAD.
BUT YOU'RE IN CONTROL OF THOSE
FEELS.
AND YOUR 10-YEAR-OLD IS GOING TO
WANT TO KNOW FROM YOU THAT
THEY'RE SAFE.
THAT YOU'RE KEEPING THEM SAFE.
THAT THEIR WORLD IS GOING ON.
THAT THEIR ROUTINES ARE GOING
ON.
AND THE BAD PERSON HAS BEEN
CAUGHT AND LIFE GOES ON.
>> RICH, THANKS VERY MUCH.
>>> LET'S GO BACK TO ELIZABETH
WITH DR. JEN ASHTON.
>> THAT'S RIGHT, GEORGE.
AND DR. ASHTON, I WAS WONDERING
ABOUT THE FACT THAT MY KIDS
DON'T YET KNOW ABOUT THIS.
A LOT OF KIDS DON'T.
WE'RE KEEPING THE TV OFF.
AT SOME POINT, THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST SAID DON'T BRING IT
UP IF THEY DON'T ASK ABOUT IT.
IS THAT THE RIGHT THING TO DO?
>> I THINK THE CHANCES OF THEM
NOT HEARING ABOUT IT IN SOME
FASHION ARE SLIM TO NONE.
I GOT A NOTICE FROM MY
CHILDREN'S SCHOOL, AS WELL,
ABOUT STEPS THEY PLAN TO TAKE AT
THE SCHOOL ON MONDAY.
IT'S IMPORTANT FOR PARENTS TO
REMEMBER THAT HOW THEY DEAL WITH
THEIR CHILDREN, HAS TO BE BASED
ON AGE.
THE CONVERSATION YOU HAVE WITH A
5-YEAR-OLD IS VERY DIFFERENT
THAN A CONVERSATION YOU HAVE
WITH A 15-YEAR-OLD.
I THINK IT'S ALSO IMPORTANT TO
REMEMBER THAT THERE MAY BE A
SPECTRUM OF REACTIONS FROM
CHILDREN WHO WERE NOT AT THE
SCENE.
IT MIGHT BE MILD.
IT MIGHT BE SEVERE.
AND IT MIGHT BE DELAYED.
IT MIGHT NOT APPEAR RIGHT AWAY.
>> IT'S IMPORTANT TO STAY CALM
WHILE YOU'RE TALKING WITH YOUR
CHILD ABOUT THIS.
AND TO REASSURE THEM, THAT EVEN
THOUGH WE CAN'T TELL THEM YOU
WILL ABSOLUTELY BE SAFE AT
SCHOOL, SAY IT ANYWAY.
GUARANTEE THEM.
>> THAT'S KEY.
YOU WANT TO KEEP THOSE HONEST
COMMUNICATIONS OPEN.
YOU WANT TO ASK THEM QUESTIONS.
BUT YOU ALSO WANT TO LISTEN.
AND I THINK IT CAN'T BE
EMPHASIZED ENOUGH THAT THIS IS A
PERFECT EXAMPLE WHERE RECRUITING
THE ASSISTANCE OF TRAINED MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS IS VITALLY
IMPORTANT.
KIDS SOMETIMES CAN'T ASK FOR
HELP.
BUT ADULTS CAN.
>> DR. ASHTON, THANKS FOR YOUR
ADVICE.
>>> WE'RE BACK TO GEORGE IN JUST
A MOMENT.
Drug and alcohol abuse is up.
And those dealing with grief
don't have access to the
professional help they need.
When you see these issues, do
you want to walk away or
step up?
With a degree in the field of
Counseling or Psychology from
Capella University, you'll have
the knowledge to make
a difference in the lives of
others.
Let's get started at
CAPELLA.EDU
THE LATEST THING
TO WEAR WITH BEAUTIFUL TOPS.
BEAUTIFUL UNDERARMS.
WEAR WITH TOGA TOPS,
YOGA TOPS, AND VA-VA-VOOM TOPS.
Dove Go Sleeveless
MAKES UNDERARMS SOFT AND SMOOTH
IN JUST FIVE DAYS.
EFFECTIVE PROTECTION.
BEAUTIFUL RESULT.
ADVIL PM® OR TYLENOL PM.
THE ADVIL PM® GUY
IS SPENDING LESS TIME
LYING AWAKE
WITH ANNOYING ACHES AND PAINS
AND MORE TIME ASLEEP.
ADVIL PM®. THE DIFFERENCE
IS A BETTER NIGHT'S SLEEP.
WITH ANNOYING ACHES AND PAINS
AND MORE TIME ASLEEP.
HE IS A GOOD LITTLE MONKEY
AND ALWAYS VERY CURIOUS.
ONE DAY GEORGE GOT
AN IMPORTANT LETTER.
HE'S BUILT A ROCKET SHIP
TO TRAVEL INTO SPACE."
GOOGLE, HOW FAR IS EARTH
TO THE MOON?
THE MOON IS 238,900 MILES...
"THE GREAT MOMENT HAD COME."
3, 2, 1...
[ GIGGLING ]
LIVING WITH MODERATE TO
SEMEANS LIVING WITH PAIN.IS
IT COULD ALSO MEAN
LIVING WITH JOINT DAMAGE.
HELP RELIEVE THE PAIN
AND STOP THE DAMAGE
WITH HUMIRA, ADALIMUMAB.
FOR MANY ADULTS WITH
MODERATE TO SEVERE RA,
HUMIRA IS CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO HELP RELIEVE PAIN
AND STOP JOINT DAMAGE.
SO YOU CAN TREAT MORE
THAN JUST THE PAIN.
HUMIRA CAN LOWER YOUR
ABILITY TO FIGHT INFECTIONS,
INCLUDING TUBERCULOSIS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL EVENTS,
SUCH AS INFECTIONS, LYMPHOMA,
OR OTHER TYPES OF
CANCER, HAVE HAPPENED.
BLOOD, LIVER AND
NERVOUS SYSTEM PROBLEMS,
SERIOUS ALLERGIC REACTIONS,
AND NEW OR WORSENING HEART
FAILURE HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING HUMIRA, YOUR
DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU FOR TB.
ASK YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU LIVE
IN OR HAVE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL
INFECTIONS ARE COMMON.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU
HAVE HAD TB, HEPATITIS B,
ARE PRONE TO INFECTIONS
OR HAVE SYMPTOMS SUCH AS
FEVER, FATIGUE, COUGH, OR SORES.
YOU SHOULD NOT START HUMIRA IF
YOU HAVE ANY KIND OF INFECTION.
ASK YOUR RHEUMATOLOGIST ABOUT
HUMIRA, TO HELP RELIEVE PAIN
AND STOP FURTHER JOINT DAMAGE
BEFORE THEY STOP YOU.
>>> YOU SEE THE GRIEF HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, TODAY.
AFTER 27 DEAD IN THE WORST
SHOOTING EVER AT AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
I'M GEORGE STEPHANOPOULOS,
JOINED HERE BY MY "GMA WEEKEND"
COLLEAGUE, DAN HARRIS.
AND, DAN, YOU DRIVE UP HERE.
IT'S THE DEFINITION OF BUCOLIC,
RURAL CONNECTICUT.
WE ASK THIS QUESTION.
HOW COULD IT HAPPEN IN A PLACE
LIKE THIS?
>> EVERY TIME WE RUSH IN TO
COVER THE AFTERMATH OF ONE OF
THESE MASS SHOOTINGS, WE HEAR
THE SAME THING.
PEOPLE SAYING, HOW COULD IT
HAPPEN TO US?
AND RARELY HAS THAT QUESTION
EVER RUNG SO TRUE, AS HERE.
NEWTOWN IS A CLASSIC, SMALL,
SLEEPY, NEW ENGLAND HAMLET.
HOME TO FEWER THAN 30,000
PEOPLE, 60 MILES NORTH OF NEW
YORK CITY.
FOUNDED IN 1705, IT PLAYED A
ROLE IN THE REVOLUTIONARY WAR
AND THE UNDERGROUND RAILROAD.
THIS IS THE PLACE WHERE THE GAME
SCRABBLE WAS INVENTED, WHERE THE
TOWN'S SYMBOL IS A ROOSTER.
WHERE PEOPLE MOVE PRECISELY FOR
SAFETY AND SCHOOLS.
>> PEOPLE COME TO NEWTOWN FOR
THE SCHOOLS.
THE HUSBANDS WILL SACRIFICE THE
COMMUTE JUST TO COME TO NEWTOWN
BECAUSE IT'S A LITTLE BIT
FARTHER THAN ANYWHERE ELSE.
>> Reporter: THIS BEAUTIFUL,
BUCOLIC SPOT IS A STRANGE,
SURREAL BACKDROP FOR TACTICAL
TEAMS IN FULL BODY ARMOR, WITH
LONG GUNS DRAWN.
>> IT DOESN'T EVEN SEEM REAL.
REALLY?
HERE IN NEWTOWN?
THIS SMALL TOWN.
YOU READ ABOUT THIS EVERYWHERE
ELSE BUT HERE.
AND IT'S HEART WRENCHING FOR THE
CHILDREN.
FOR THE PARENTS AND GRANDPARENTS
AND EVERYBODY.
>> Reporter: IT FEELS LIKE A
DREAM AND A BAD DREAM.
>> IT'S A NIGHTMARE.
>> Reporter: AS REALITY SINKS IN
HERE, THE FEELING THAT ONE LOCAL
DESCRIBED AS MAGICAL INSULATION,
HAS BEEN TRULY SHATTERED.
AND THE REALIZATION IS DAWNING
THAT NEWTOWN IS NOW IN THE
HISTORY BOOKS FOR THE WORST OF
ALL POSSIBLE REASONS.
>> THEY KEEP SAYING ON THE TV,
NEWTOWN'S SUCH A NICE TOWN.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
NICE TOWN, NOT A NICE TOWN.
IT COULD HAPPEN ANYWHERE.
>> ON A PERSONAL NOTE, I USED TO
COME HERE AS A CHILD.
WE HAD FAMILY HERE.
AND I REMEMBER VIVIDLY PLAYING
IN THE QUIET CUL-DE-SACS WITH
THE OTHER LITTLE KIDS.
THIS REALLY BRINGS HOME QUITE
POWERFULLY THAT IT CAN HAPPEN
ANYWHERE.
>> AND A TOWN THIS SMALL, EVERY,
SINGLE PERSON TOUCHED.
>> INDEED.
>> WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
THE USUAL, BOB?
NOT TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
BOB HAS AFIB:
ATRIAL FIBRILLATION NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
A CONDITION THAT PUTS HIM
AT GREATER RISK FOR A STROKE.
[ GPS ] TURN LEFT.
I DON'T THINK SO.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR YEARS, BOB TOOK WARFARIN,
AND MADE A MONTHLY TRIP TO THE
CLINIC TO GET HIS BLOOD TESTED.
BUT NOT ANYMORE.
BOB'S DOCTOR RECOMMENDED
A DIFFERENT OPTION:
ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
XARELTO® IS THE FIRST AND ONLY
ONCE-A-DAY PRESCRIPTION
BLOOD THINNER
FOR PATIENTS WITH AFIB
NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
THAT DOESN'T REQUIRE
ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING.
LIKE WARFARIN,
XARELTO® IS PROVEN EFFECTIVE
TO REDUCE THE RISK
OF AN AFIB-RELATED STROKE.
THERE IS LIMITED DATA
ON HOW THESE DRUGS COMPARE
WHEN WARFARIN IS WELL MANAGED.
NO ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING
MEANS BOB CAN SPEND HIS
EXTRA TIME HOWEVER HE LIKES.
NEW ZEALAND!
XARELTO®
IS JUST ONE PILL A DAY,
TAKEN WITH THE EVENING MEAL.
AND WITH
NO DIETARY RESTRICTIONS,
BOB CAN EAT THE HEALTHY FOODS
HE LIKES.
DO NOT STOP TAKING
XARELTO® RIVAROXABAN
WITHOUT TALKING TO THE DOCTOR
WHO PRESCRIBES IT FOR YOU.
STOPPING MAY INCREASE YOUR RISK
OF HAVING A STROKE.
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU DEVELOP ANY SIGNS
OR SYMPTOMS OF BLEEDING,
LIKE UNUSUAL BRUISING
OR TINGLING.
YOU MAY HAVE A HIGHER RISK
OF BLEEDING
IF YOU TAKE XARELTO®
WITH ASPIRIN PRODUCTS,
NSAIDS OR BLOOD THINNERS.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE TAKING XARELTO®
IF YOU CURRENTLY HAVE
ABNORMAL BLEEDING.
XARELTO® CAN CAUSE BLEEDING,
WHICH CAN BE SERIOUS,
AND RARELY MAY LEAD TO DEATH.
YOU ARE LIKELY TO BRUISE
MORE EASILY ON XARELTO®,
AND IT MAY TAKE LONGER
FOR BLEEDING TO STOP.
TELL YOUR DOCTORS
YOU ARE TAKING XARELTO®
BEFORE ANY PLANNED MEDICAL
OR DENTAL PROCEDURES.
BEFORE STARTING XARELTO®,
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ANY CONDITIONS,
SUCH AS KIDNEY, LIVER
OR BLEEDING PROBLEMS.
READY TO CHANGE YOUR ROUTINE?
ASK YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
FOR MORE INFORMATION
INCLUDING COST SUPPORT OPTIONS,
CALL 1-888-XARELTO
OR VISIT GOXARELTO.COM.
>>> WE WILL BE REPORTING FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, ALL DAY
LONG HERE ON ABC NEWS.
STAY WITH US.
>>> A SHOOTING OVERNIGHT HAS
LEFT A TEENAGE BOY IN CRITICAL
CONDITION.
HE WAS SHOT BY FOUR MEN IN A
PASSING CAR AROUND 1:30 THIS
MORNING.
THE VICTIM WAS ABLE TO WALK TO
SAN FRANCISCO GENERAL HOSPITAL.
>> IN JUST A FEW MINUTES, SAN
FRANCISCO WILL HOLD THE BAY
AREA'S LATEST VIGIL FOR
YESTERDAY'S SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT.
LAST NIGHT PARENTS AND STUDENTS
TURNED OUT AT THIS CANDLELIGHT
VIGIL IN MILL VALLEY.
COMING UP WE'LL HAVE A LIVE
REPORT FROM THE PRAYER SERVICE
IN GOLDEN GATE.
HERE IS LISA ARGEN WITH THE
WEATHER.
>> GOOD MORNING.
WE HAVE LIGHT RAIN THAT WILL BE
DEVELOPING TODAY.
IT WILL BE MODERATE OVER PARTS
OF THE BAY.
RIGHT NOW, LOOKING AT SUNSHINE.
YOU'LL SEE MORE OF IT IN THE
SOUTH BAY, ESPECIALLY IN THE
MORNING HOURS.
RIGHT NOW, LOOK AT LIVE DOPPLER
7-HD.
MOST OF THE MOISTURE WELL TO THE
NORTH OF US, IT'S CHILLY OUT
THERE, 32 IN LIVERMORE.
FOG AROUND 580 AND FOG IN THE
NORTH BAY.
37 IN SAN RAFAEL.
HERE IS THE SYSTEM THAT IS A
WEAK ONE.
AS IT MOVES THROUGH AROUND 11:00
THIS MORNING, WE'LL SEE RAIN
SPREADING IN THE AFTERNOON.
SPOTTY SHOWERS, HERE WE ARE
SUNDAY MORNING AND FEW MORE
SHOWERS, BUT MOST OF THE RAIN
OCCURS TODAY.
RAINFALL AMOUNTS VERY LIGHT WITH
THIS SYSTEM.
JUST TRACE AMOUNTS TO THE SOUTH.
SECOND SYSTEM HEADS OUR WAY
MONDAY MORNING.
SEVERAL DAYS OF RAIN TO TALK
ABOUT.
WE'LL HAVE THAT FOR YOU COMING
UP.
>> "ABC 7 NEWS" [ Male Announce]
THERE'S CHICKEN
AND THERE'S JUICY CHICKEN
BEST FOODS IS THE SECRET
TO MAKING
PARMESAN CRUSTED CHICKEN
SO JUICY
SO DELICIOUS
IT'S YOUR SECRET
TO MAKING DINNER
DISAPPEAR
BEST FOODS.
BRING OUT THE BEST
FOR STRONG BEAUTIFUL HAIR.
-IT TURNS OUT...
-WE WERE WORKING AT...
AT THE WRONG END OF HAIR.
[ Male Announcer ]
INTRODUCING CLEAR.
IT FEEDS YOUR SCALP.
CLEAR GIVES YOU STRONGER
MORE BEAUTIFUL HAIR.
[ Heidi ] CLEAR SCALP
AND HAIR BEAUTY THERAPY.
>>> WHEN I SAW THE TEACHERS AND
LOCKED EYES SEPARATELY, SAW THE
TWO CHILDREN, IF I COULD GO BACK
I WOULD EMBRACE THEM.
>> THE FATHER OF SANDY HOOK
STUDENTS TALKS ABOUT FINDING
PEOPLE ALIVE.
PARENTS OF THE VICTIMS ARE
ASKING FOR PRIVACY.
I'M KATIE MARZULLO.
CONNECTICUT POLICE HAVE GIVEN AN
UPDATE INTO THEIR INVESTIGATION.
THIS IS WHAT WE KNOW.
SOME OF THE VICTIMS' BOES