PENN.
I'M RACHEL SMITH.
WELL THIS SHOW IS ABOUT THE
PRESIDENT.
LOOK AT THE SET.
WE'RE IN SIDE OF THE OVAL
VIS.
WE'LL SHOW YOU AROUND AND
TALK TO THE STARS, BUT
FIRST, THE BIG NEWS THIS WE
CAN, THELE GONE GLOB
NOMINATIONS.
ENTERTAINMENT GURU GEORGE
PENNACCHIO WAS THERE.
>> BEST MOTION PICTURE
DRAMA.
>> ARGO.
DJANDO UNCHAINED LIFE OF
LINCOLN, ZERO DARK THIRTY.
>> LINCOLN LEASED THE WAY
WITH SEVEN GOLDEN GLOBE
NOMINATIONS INCLUDING ONES
FOR DIRECTOR STEVEN
SPIELBERG AND STARS.
BEN AFFLECK'S ARGO AND
QUINTIN TARANTINO UNCHAINED
ARE TIED FOR SECOND PLACE
WITH FIVE NOMINATIONS EACH.
>> BEST MOTION PICTURE
COMEDY OR MUSICAL THE BEST
EXOTIC MARIGOLD HOTEL LAME
IS A ROB, THAT'S THE CORRECT
PRONUNNATION, MOONRISE
KINGDOM, SALMON FISHING IN
THE YEMEN AND SILVER
LOONINGS PLAYBOOK.
ON THE TV SIDE BEST DRAMA
NOMINEES INCLUDE BREAKING
BAD, BOARDWALK EMPIRE,
DOWNTON ABBEY, HOMELAND, AND
NEWSROOM FOR BEST COMEDY.
THE BIG BANG THEORY, CBS,
EPISODES, SHOW TIME, GIRLS
HBO, MODERN FAMILY, ABC,
SMASH, NBC.
>> ACT NOMINEES INCLUDE
SOFIA VERGARA AND ERIC STONE
STREET FOR MODERN FAMILY.
TINA FEY AND AMY POEHLER ARE
BOTH UP FOR BEST ACTRESS IN
TV COMEDY.
THE PAIR WILL ALSO HOST THE
SHOW.
CHECK OUT THE FULL LIST OF
NOMINEES AT
ONTHEREDCARPET.COM.
>> SOME OF THE GOLDEN GLOBE
NOMINEES GET EVEN MORE GOOD
NEWS THIS WEEK FROM THE
SCREEN ACTORS GUILD!
>> DANIEL DAY-LEWIS.
>> YES A CHASTAIN, ANNE
HATHAWAY.
>> HUGH JACKMAN.
>> BUSY PHILLIPS AND TAYE
ANNOUNCED THE NOMINEES FOR
THE 2013 SAG AWARDS AND TELL
US WHO THEY ARE ROOTING FOR.
>> A MOVIE THAT I LOVED,
WHICH SOMETIMES YOU DONE
KNOW HOW OTHER PEOPLE ARE
GOING TO RECEIVE IT IN SUCH
A WAY WAS SILVER LININGS
PLAYBOOK.
IT REALLY STAYED WITH ME AND
IT IS NICE TO KNOW THAT
OTHER PEOPLE THOUGHT THE
SAME.
>> I LOVE EVERYONE THAT WAS
NOMINATED TODAY.
>> 'S SO EXCITED TO SEE A
FEW THINGS THAT I HAVEN'T
SEEN YET.
>> SILVER LININGS PLAYBOOK,
LES MISERABLES AND LINCOLN
HAVE FOUR NOMINATIONS EACH
BUT DOES THAT MEAN THEY ARE
DESTINED FOR OSCAR GOLD?
>> ON THE TV SIDE, MOD HERB
FAMILY RECEIVED A LEADING
FOUR NOMINATION.
FOR A FULL LIST OF NOMINEES
GO ON TO ON THE RED CARPET!
COM.
THE SCREEN ACTORS GUILD
AWARDS ARE LIVE JANUARY 27TH
ON TNT AND TBS.
>> IT HAS BAN BIG WEEK FOR
HUGH JACKMAN.
HE IS KNOTS JUST NOMINATED
FOR HIS ROLE IN LES
MISERABLES BUT HE RECEIVED A
ANOTHER BIG HONOR IN
HOLLYWOOD, TOO.
HE CAN SING.
CAN DANCE.
THIS WEEK HUGH JACKMAN
SHOWED US HE CAN SMILE.
HE DUG HIS CLAWS INTO
HOLLYWOOD HISTORY WITH STAR
ON THE LEGENDARY WALK OF
FAME.
A THIS IS THE 2487TH STAR ON
THE WALK OF FAME; HOWEVER,
APARTED FROM LASSIE, I AM
THE ONLY ONE TO GET IT FOR
THE PLAYING THE SAME
CHARACTERS IN 15 MOVIES,
SO --
>> HUGH'S PALS AND CO STARS
JOINED THE FRENZY OF FANS
LINED UP TO CATCH A GLIMPSE
OF THE CEREMONY.
>> I HAVE THE GREATEST FANS
IN THE WORLD ABLE KNOW THAT
IS AN EASY THING TO SAY FOR
ACTORS AND I DON'T TAKE THIS
IT LIGHTLY OR TAKE IT FOR
GRANTED AND THANK YOU SO
MUCH FOR ALL YOU DO.
>> NONE OF THIS WOULD HAVE
BEEN POSSIBLE AND CERTAINLY
NONE OF THIS WOULD HAVE BEENEWAR
AS REWARDING OR MEANINGFUL
TOLL ME IF NOT FOR MY
FAMILY.
>> LOOK AT MY LITTLE
PHOTOGRAPHER DAUGHTER.
KIDS, YOU DON'T REALLY
UNDERSTAND IT NOW, BUT
AREA'S GOING TO SAVE A
FORTUNE IN THERAPY BUY
COMING HERE AND SPITTING ON
IT, JUMPING ON IT, ALL THOSE
THINGS, THAT I ANNOYED YOU,
YOU CAN COME AND TAKE IT OUT
ON HERE.
SORRY TO THE CITY OF LOS
ANGELES.
I CAN SEE HIM IN LAME IS A
ROB IN THEATERS ON CHRISTMAS
DAY.
>> YOU KNOW WHO ELSE HAS A
STAR?
BARBARA STRIES STAND AND
OTRC'S TONICA BRAIR HIT THE
RED CARPET FOR THE PREMIER
OF HER NEW MOVIE THE GUILT
TRIP.
>> RACHEL THE LAST TIME
BARBARA STRIES STANDARDED AS
A LEADING LADY WAS 16 YEAR
AGO.
NOW SHE IS BACK TON THE
SCREEN THIS TIME WITH SETH
ROGEN.
>> IT WAS TIME FOR KNOW COME
BACK AND DO A FULL LENGTH
MOTION PICTURE.
AND I WAS GETTING A LITTLE
BORED IN MY LIFE AND
HELL.D, WHAT THE
TOOK YEAR TO CONVINCE ME WAS
REALLY FUN.
I AM GLAD I IT DID.
>> SETH YOU HAVE GOT TO FEEL
HONORED THAT SHE SAID YES
AFTER ALL THESE.
>> ON THE I HAVE, SETH PLAYS
BARB BR'S SON WHO ENDS UP
TAKING HER ALONG AN8 DAY
ROAD TRIP.
>> SETH, A ARE YOU DOING,
MOM?
>> PLEASE TURN THAT OFF.
MOM.
>> GET OFF THE FREEWAY.
>> BARBARA SAYS HER REAL
LIFE SON IS PRETTY SHY
UNLIKE THE MAN WHO CALLS HER
MOM IN THE MOVIE.
>> SETH IS RIGHT OUT THERE.
YOU KNOW, HE IS NOT AFRID TO
SAY WHAT HE THINKS AND MAKE
JOKE, TALK DIRT WHERE I,
PULL DOWN HIS PANTS.
I HAD TO WATCH THAT.
I HAD TO TELL HIM KEEP YOUR
PANTS ON.
KEEP YOUR PANTS ON.
>> SHOULD I GO TO THIS MOVIE
WITH MY MOM?
>> OR THAT IS A BAD GLAD TO
I THINK IT IS A GRETTED
YESTERDAY.
YOU SHOULD SEE IT WITH YOUR
MOM.
>> THE GUILT TRIP IS IN
THEATERS WEDNESDAY.
>> NOW THERE IS A SEQUEL.
THIS IS 40 WITH RETURNING
STARS LESLIE MANN AND PAUL
RUDD.
>> YOU KNOW WHAT 40'S ABOUT
RIGHT, WHAT IS 40 TO YOU?
ITE IS ABOUT TURNING 40 BUT
SEEMS LIKE IT IS, IT IS
WORKING OUT, LIKE IT IS
OKAY.
I FEEL PRETTY GOOD ABOUT IT.
AND BUT IT DEFENSE ON THE
DAY.
SOME DAYS I'M NOT FEELING AS
GOOD ABOUT IT.
LIKE WHEN I SEE LITTLE GRY
HAIRS HERE AND THERE.
>> I DON'T THINK 40 IS SO
DIFFERENT THAN 39 OR ANY
THING ABOUT IT DOES SOUND,
IT DOES FORM ON THE LIPS
DIFFERENTLY.
IT HAS A SOUND TO IT.
BUT I THINK IT IS MORE
ABOUT, THE MARKER THAT TELLS
YOU YOU ARE IN A SECTION OF
YOUR LIFE.
YOU ARE JUST KIND OF LIKE
AREA'S IN THE MID OF IT.
>> MY HUSBAND IS MUCH ORDER
THAN ME.
HE WILL ALWAYS THINK OF ME
AS TROPHY WIFE.
SO I DON'T HAVE TO WORRY.
WHEN I AM 40 HE WILL BE 53
SO WHAT THERE IS TO WORRY
ABOUT?
>> AND EVEN THOUGH THE MOVIE
ISN'T EXACTLY FAMILY
FRIENDLY.
IT WAS TO DIRECTOR JUDD WHO
CAST HIS WIFE LESLIE AND
THEIR TWO DAUGHTERS.
THIS IS 40 HITS THEATERS
>> COMING UP, PETER JACKSON
BRINGS THE HOBBIT TO LIFE.
WE ARE AT POINT WHERE YOU
CAN LITERALLY CLOSE YOUR
EYES.
>> BREAKING A THE SECRETS
TWO OF BROKE GIRLS.
>> I CAN'T GIVE ANYTHING
AWAY.
HE CAN'T GIVEAWAY ANYTHING
ON THE SHOW.
IT IS SO TIGHT!
>> AND MEETING THE FIRST FAM
LOVE LAUGHS.
THE CAST OF 1600 PENN.
>> IT IS STRANGE YOU KNOW.
IT IS EXCITING!
>> GET TWEETS FROM
HOLLYWOOD.
>> FOLLOW ON THE RED CARPET
AND RACHEL OTRC ON TWITTER!
>> HI, I'M JENNA ELFMAN AND
YOU ARE WATCHING ON THE RED
ñ
>> LOS ANGELES FILM CRITICS
ASSOCIATION CHOSE AMOUR THE
SKIP, I THINK IT IS TIME FOR
TO YOU COME HOME FROM
SCHOOL.
SEVEN YEARS OOLLEGES
PLENTY.
>> I'M THREE CREDITS SHY OF
GRADUATING.
YOU SAID THAT LAST YEAR.
DOESN'T MAKE IT LESS TRUE.
>> WELCOME BACK TO ON THE
RED CARPET FROM THE NBC SHOW
1 00 PENN.
IT AM HANGING OUT HERE AT
PRESIDENT'S DESK AND WHAT
THE STARS AND YOU BIT BUT
FIRST IF YOU ARE GOING TO
TALK ABOUT AMAZING SETS,
GEORGE IS TACKING US BACK TO
MIDDLE EARTH.
THAT'S IN THIS WEEK'S MER
SAY DES BENZ STAR SPOTLIGHT!♪
♪
>> LET'S BEEN A DECADE SINCE
AUDIENCES FIRST FOUND MIDDLE
EARTH.
NOW DIRECTOR PETER JACKSON
TAKES US BACK LIKE WE'VE
NEVER SEEN IT BEFORE.
>> I'M LUCKY THAT THE LAST
TEN YEARS SINCE THE LORD OF
THE RNGS TECHNOLOGY HAS
ADVANCED QUIT A LONG WAY, SO
YOU KNOW, WE ARE AT POINT
WHERE YOU CAN LITERALLY
CLOSE YOUR EYES AND IMAGINE
ANYTHING, AND PUT THAT ON
SCREEN NOW.
THERE'S NO OBSTACLES
ANYMORE.
>> BUT PLENTY OFS ON KELLS
STAND IN THE WAY OF THE
HOBBIT ON HIS UNEXPECTED
JOURNEY.
>> WHEN I'M WATCHING THIS
MOVIE, I FEEL LIKE I AM
SEEING THROUGH THE ICE OF A
CHILD SOMETIMES.
CAUSE HE IS WITH THESE GUYS
WHO ARE ROUGH AND TUMBLE AND
HE IS WIDE EYED.
>> ABSOLUTELY, YEAH.
AND IT WAS NICE TO PLY,
CAUSE I'M NOT PARTICULARLY
LIKE THAT.
SO THAT WAS MY BEST ACTING
RIGHT THERE.
>> MARTIN FREEMAN PLAYS THE
HABIT.
JUMPING INTO THOSE LEGENDARY BEN
ADVENTURE ITS OWN.
>> ALL THE STUFF THAT IS
HAPPENING NOW, THE POSTERS
AND THE LUNCH BOX SIDE OF
IT.
I'LL GOT SWAY OVER THAT, GOT
NO CONTROL, SO YOU JUST KIND
OF GO ALONG WITH THE RIDE
WITH IT.
>> ALONG FOR THAT RIDE ARE
SOME FAMILIAR FACES WHO
LOVED SLIPPING BACK INTO
THEIR CHARACTERS.
>> THE COSTUME ALONE LOOKED
EXHAUSTING.
>> MY COSTUME'S, I HAD AN
EASY TIME OF IT.
THE DWARVES HAVE GOT A FALSE
HEAD, AND FALSE HANDS, AND
FALSE LEGS.
THEY WERE CARRYING GREAT
WEIGHTS ON THEIR BACK,
DURING THE JOURNEYS, I'VE
SEEN THEM AT THE END OF
TAKES.
JUST LITERALLY FALL BACK AND
LEAN AGAINST THE TREE.
>> THAT WAS THE ROLE THAT
REALLY ENABLED ME TO MY ALL
THE OTHERS AND LIKE I SAID
PUSHED THAT TECHNOLOGY
FORWARD.
HE JUST KIND OF RUNS A WHOLE
SPECTRUM OF EMOTIONS.
>> CATCH THE HOBBIT, AN
UNEXPECTED JURN NIN THEATERS
NOW.
♪ FROM MIDDLE EARTH TO THE
MOUNTAINS OF PAKISTAN.
THE HISTORICAL AT THE
THRILLER ZERO DARK THIS TY
RON KELLS THE GREATEST
MANHUNT IN HUMAN HISTORY.
>> WHERE WAS THE LAST TIME
YOU SAW BIN LADEN?
>> THE STARS TRADED THEIR
FATIGUES FOR MORE
FASHIONABLE THREADS AT THE
HOLLYWOOD RED CARPET
PREMIER.
>> THIS MOVIE INTRODUCES US
TO A VERY STRONG, INCREDIBLE
WOMAN NAMED MAYA WHO WAS AT
THE CENTER OF THE GREATEST
MANHUNT IN HISTORY.
>> IT BOWS BACK TO, YOU
KNOW, THE MEN AND WOMEN THAT
ARE OUT THERE, YOU KNOW,
PUNCHING THE CLOCK, DOING
THE DAY-IN, DAY-OUT WORK AND
I KNOW PEOPLE DON'T KNOW
THAT STORY.
>> I THINK JUST THROW OUT
EVERYTHING YOU'VE HEARD AND
JUST YOU KNOW BUCKLE IN FOR
IT IS QUITE EX INTENSE EX
FROM ORDINARY RIDE.
IT IS OSCAR-WINNING DIRECTOR
KATHRYN BIGELOW'S FIRST
FILM.
>> IT IS KIND OF LIKE A
TOP-SECRET FILL, SO YOU'LL
BE LEFT OUT OF THE
CONVERSATION IF YOU DON'T
SITE.
>> IF YOU'RE RIGHT, THE
WHOLE WORLD'S GOING WANT TO
KNOW THIS.
>> THE HUNT BEGINS IN
LIMITED RELEASE WEDNESDAY.
>> UP NEXT, THE WHITE HOUSE
HAS NEVER BEEN THIS FUNNY!
>> NOT A GOOD DAY GOES BY
WHERE I DON'T FEEL LIKE I'M
LIVING IN THE WHITE HOUSE.
>> JOKING AROUND WITH JAMES
VANDERBEEK.
>> AND LEARNING SOME MOVES
FROM A DISNEY PRINCESS!
>> GO BEHIND THE SCENES WITH
OTRC.
BECOME A FAN OF ON THE RED A
PET ON FACEBOOK!
AND DON'T FORGET, YOU CAN
SUBSCRIBE TO RACHEL'S
FACEBOOK PAGE, TOO.
>> HI.
>> 'S JAMES VANDERBEEK, I
PLAY JAMES
[ Boy 1 ] Hey!
That's the last Crescent.
Oh, did you want it?
Yea
We'll split it.
[ Female Announcer ]
Made fresh, so light,
buttery and flakey.
That's half
That's not half!
Guys, I have more!
Thanks Mom
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Crescents.
Let the Making Begin
[ Female Announcer ]
HOLIDAY COOKIES ARE A BIG JOB.
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE
JUST RIGHT.
PERFECTION IS IN THE DETAILS.
♪
GET TO HOLIDAY FUN FASTER
WITH PILLSBURY COOKIE DOUGH.
>> BACK ON THE SET OF 1 00
PENN, TAKE A LOOK AT THIS.
WE ARE NOW INSIDE OF THE
RESIDENCE OF THE FIRST
FAMILY.
>> A FUNNY LOOK AT WHAT LIFE
MAY BE LIKE AT THE MOST
FAMOUS ADDRESS IN AMERICA.
>> SKIP DON'T SIT IN MY
CHAIR.
>> ON 1600 PENN, BILL PULMAN
PLAYS THE PRESIDENT, AGAIN!
>> IT WAS SO WILD, THAT
FIRST DAVE SHOOTING IN THE
OVAL OFFICE.
AND COUPLE OF THE GRIPS CAME
OVER AND SAID BILL WE JUST
WANT TO SAY THIS IS SO WEIRD
OF HAVING ONLY KNOWN YOU IN
THE OVAL OFFICE FROM
INDEPENDENCE DY AND NOW HERE
WE'RE SHOOTING IN THE OVAL
OFFICE.
I DON'T KNOW AREA'S JUST
PERFECT PRESIDENT SO I
UNDERSTAND WHY YOU'VE BEEN
HIRED TWICE.
>> JOSH GAD PLAYS
IRRESPONSIBLE BUT LOVABLE
FIRST SON.
>> THERE'S NOT A CHARACTER
YOU DONE LOVE.
THAT'S WHAT MAKES THE SHOW
CLICK IS THAT IT IS A
FAMILY.
IT RUNS RELATABLE FAMILY.
THEIR FATHER JUST HAPPENS TO
BE THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES.
>> IT IS REALLY FUN SHOW AND
THE CHARACTERS ARE ALL
INTERESTING ANEW NOOKLY
CARVED.
A LOT OF LOVE.
>> JOSH CREATED THE SHOW
WITH HIS FRIENDS A FORMER
MODERN FALLLY DIRECTON AUN
WITH OF PRESIDENT OBAMA'S
FORMER SPEECHWRITERS!
>> THERE ARE DEFINITELY
TIMES WHEN I WALK ASH THE
WEST WING SET AND I FEEL A
LITTLE BIT OF DAY JA VIEW.
>> THIS ISN'T A POLITICAL
SHOW AT ALL BUT HOPEFULLY
SOME AM OF THE THINGS I'VE
SEEN WHETHER IT IS FROM THE
PRESS OR FROM CONPRESS FROM
WHEREVER JUST PROVIDES A
LITTLE BIT OF FODDER TO TELL
A STORY ABOUT THE FAMILY.
>> WE HAVE AN ORDINARY
FAMILY WITH ITS UNUSUAL
DYNAMIC, DYSFUNCTION AND
CRAZINESSNESS THE MOST
HEIGHTENED SETTING IN
AMERICA.
>> 1 00 PENN IS A FUNNY SHOW
IN A GAR REASON TU YOU WILL
ENJOY IT.
>> CATCH THE SNEAK PEEK OF
1600 PENN MONDAY ON NBC!
>> OVER ON ABC'S DON'T TRUST
THE B IN APARTMENT 23 THE
CAST TELLS US THERE'S STILL
PLENTY OF TROUBLE TO COME.
>> OH, DON'T EVER PUT A
LIMIT ON THE AMOUNT OF
TROUBLE WE CAN CONJURE UP.
BELIEVE ME.
THESE GIRLS ARE, WE'RE ALL
CRAZY.
>> YOU KNOW, UM, MY JAW IS
ON THE GROUND EVERY WEEK.
THESE WRITERS ARE SO
TWISTED.
THEY JUST KEEP COMING UPORE DANR
FOR US TO GET INTO.
>> WAND THE HOLIDAYS ROLLING
IN, WHAT DO THEY THINK THEIR
CHARACTERS WILL CHOOSE FOR
NEW YEAR'S RESOLUTIONS?
>> HER RESOLUTION IS TO
PROBABLY HIT THE BIGGEST
PARTIES OF THE YEAR.
>> SO IT WOULD BE PROBABLY
BE SOMETHING FITNESS
ORIENTED OR LIKE YOU KNOW
SOME WEIRD STRANGE JUICE
THAT SHE INSISTS ON DRINKING
EVER DAY.
>> HIS NEW YEAR'S RESOLUTION
WOULD PROBABLY BE, UM, STEP
UP THE HAIR CARE, MAKE SURE,
PUT A LITTLE MORE TIME INTO
THE HAIR, CATCH DON'T TRUST
THE B IN APARTMENT 23
TUESDAY NIGHT ON ABC.
>> OVER ON 2 BROKE GIRLS,
MATTHEW MOY IS HOLDING IT
DOWN AS THE TARGET OF JOKES
DINER OWNER.
OFFSET THOUGH, HE SAYS THE
LAUGHS ARE WIDESPREAD!
>> BETH'S A GOOFBALL.
ME AND JONATHAN, WE'RE
ALWAYS GOOFING AROUND DOING
IMPRESSIONS.
THE ONE THAT I LOVE BEST
ISLEY A.M. NEESON HE DOES
THIS GREAT TAKEN VOICE.
I CAN'T DO IT CAUSE MY VOICE
IS TOO HIGH AND WHEN I GET
LOW, IT SOUNDS LAKE MUPPET.
ONLY THE SHOW HE PLACE HIS
AGE.
LATE 20'S.
>> BUT HIS CREDITS SHOW HIM
EVERYWHERE.
>> MAN, I GET CARDED ALL THE
TIME.
I CAN FUDGE SOME THINGS
SOMETIMES.
YOUTH-WISE, BUT WHEN I DID
SCRUBS, WE WERE LIKE IN
COLLEGE, AND I WAS LIKE,
THIS IS PERFECT.
I DON'T HAVE TO BE SOME
TEENAGER WHICH I CAN, MY
ARMS LOOKS KIND OF BUFF BUT
WE CAN.
>> FOR NOW, 2 BROKE GIRLS IS
WHERE IT IS AT AND MATTHEW
IS LOVING IT!
>> I HOPE WE MEET MY FAMILY.
I HOPE WE MEET MY MOTHER
CAUSE WE TALK ABOUT HER.
>> GET BACK THE GIRLS MONDAY
NIGHTS ON CBS!
>> 15 YEARS AGO CASPER VAN
DIEN BUILT A HUGE FAN BASE
THE CULT CLASSIC, STARSHIP
TROOPERS.
>> 'S WALK DONE THE STREET
AND SOMEBODY GOES RICO, OH
MY GOD, RICO.
>> NOW HE SAYS HE HAS GOT A
ANOTHER HIT THAT WILL LIVE
ON EVERY CHRISTMAS.
THE NEW ROMANTIC HOLIDAY
MOVIE BABY'S FIRST
CHRISTMAS.
>> IT IS A FILM I WAS VERY
PROUD OF WORKING ON.
>> CHRISTMAS IS CASS FOR'S
FAVORITE TIME OF THE YEAR
PARTLY BECAUSE HIS BIRTHDAY
FALLS SO CLOSE TO THE BIG
DAY.
>> I MY MOM INDUCED A WEEK
EARLY.
I WAS DUE CHRISTMAS DAY BUT
MY FATHER WANTS THE
MILITARY.
SHE WANTED ME OUT WHILE HE
WAS THERE AND THEY DIDN'T
WANT TO BE IN THE HOSPITAL
DURING CHRISTMAS.
>> NOW THE FAMILY HAS GROWN,
ALONG WITH A COUPLE OF NEW
TRADITIONS.
>> WE GOT THE IDEA WHEN MY
KIDS WERE REALLY LITTLE,
THAT MY DAD WOULD PLAY STAN.
I KNOW THEY WERE EXCITED BUT
WE WERE ALL LIKE PUSH K THEM
OUT.
>> GET IN THE SPIRIT!
BABY'S FIRST CHRISTMAS AIRS
ON THE HALL MARK CHANNEL.
>> UP NEXT,.
>> PLAYING IT COOL WITH A
DISNEY PRINCESS.
>> AND A BIG SURPRISE FOR
THE STAR OF 1600 PENN ON THE
RED CARPET WILL RETURN RIGHT
AFTER THIS.
>> ONCE POON TIME'S SNOW
WHITE, GINNIFER
>> MONDAY, DECEMBER 17TH IS
A BUSY DAY FOR BIRTHDATION!
MILLA IS 37.
VAR PAULSON TURNS 38.
AND BILL PULMAN CELEBRATES
HIS 59th BIRTHDAY.
SINCE SINCE WE'RE ON THE SET
OF BILLION'S NEW SHOW 1600
PENN, WE HAD TO SURPRISE
HIM!
>> THIS IS GOOD I HAVEN'T
BEEN EATING SWEETS TODAY I
GUESS CUZ IT IS ALMOST MY
BOTH DAY.
I GET TO HAVE A LITTLE.
THIS IS HEAVE RY TOO.
>> HAPPY BIRTHDAY, BILL!
>> SPEAKING OF CELEBRATIONS,
KARL'S TACK US TO A MAGICAL
ONE ON THE ICE!
>> WHAT A HOLIDAY GIFT YOU
GOT ME RACHEL.
ICE SKATING LESSONS I
THOUGHT I WOULD ENLIST THE
HELP OF A PROFESSIONAL.
DISNEY ON ICE'S DARE TO
DREAM PROMISES A CELEBRATION
OF ROYAL PROPORTIONS, WHO
BETTER THAN ONE OF THE
SHOW'S SKATERS TO TEACH ME
HOW IT IS DONE.
>> OKAY.
TO LARN HOW TO SKATE FIRST I
WANT YOU TO JUST MARCH IN
PLACE LITTLE BIT.
GET USED TO THE ICE.
BEND YOUR KNEES.
YOU WANT TO KEEP YOUR BODY
DOWN CLOSE TO THE ICE.
>> THAT'S A LOT TO DO ALL AT
ONCE!
>> IT IS EASY I PROM MILLS
YOU.
>> OKAY, SO HOW ABOUT A
LITTLE SPIN?
>> OKAY PERFECT.
WHAT WE'RE GOING TO DO IS
MARCH IN POLICE A LITTLE BIT
AND GET SOME SPEED UP.
>> OR MAYBE NOT.
THE SHOW FETORS SOME OF
DISNEY'S MOST POPULAR
PRINCESSES SO I WAS DINO IF
THERE WERE ANY DIVAS AMONG
THE ROYALTY.
>> PRINCESS TIANA, THEN WE
MOVE INTO CLASSIC
CINDERELLA, AND THEN WE MOVE
INTO REPUNZEL, AND YOU KNOW
SHE HAS HER LONG HAIR AND
SHE TAKES THE MOST
MAINTENANCE TO GET HER HAIR
READY, CUZ YOU KNOW,
BRAIDING ALL THAT HAIR TAKES
IT A LOVE WORK.
CHECK OUT PRINCESSES.
>> GOOD SKATING!
ALL RIGHT.
THAT DOES IT FOR US FROM THE
SET OF THE NEW SHOW 1600
CATCH THE F.
CATCH THE FIRST EPISODE
MONDAY ON NBC.
NEXT WEEK, SITTING DOWN WITH
THE STA
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
At Yoplait,
we want you to feel
even better
about your favorite flavors.
So when you call, tweet,
and post, we listen.
That's why Yoplait Light
and Yoplait Original
are now made with
no high fructose corn syrup.
And why we use
only natural colors
and natural flavors
in Yoplait Original.
So, anything else we can do
for you, let us know.
But you'll keep it
to yogurt, right?
'Cause we shouldn't really help
with your love life.
Yoplait. It is so good!
wanted to be here
for your fist Christmas?
You see
Grandma lives waaaay down here,
and you live way up here.
Brian, your cousin, he's
a little bit older than you,
he lives here, in Chicago.
And your Aunt Lisa lives here,
in Baltimore.
Uncle Earnie?
Waaay out in Hawaii.
But don't you worry,
we will always be together
for Christmas.
[ Male Announcer ]
Being together
is the best part
of the holidays
and Cheerios is happy
to be part of the family.
You just ate Dallas!
>> Announcer: THE FOLLOWING IS A
PAID PRESENTATION FOR THE
MILANA BRA BY GENIE.
ARE YOU HAVING ANOTHER
BAD BRA DAY?
SHOULDER STRAPS AND UNDERWIRE
DIGGING IN?
HOOKS POKING YOU IN THE BACK?
ARE THE GIRLS...
WELL, OUT THERE?
>> REALLY?
YOU'RE KIDDING.
>> Announcer: NO MORE.
INTRODUCING THE MILANA BRA
BY GENIE.
IT GIVES YOU THE SUPPORT, LIFT,
FIT AND COMFORT YOU ALREADY LOVE
FROM THE ORIGINAL GENIE BRA,
PLUS THE COVERAGE OF A
BEAUTIFULLY SEWN LACE CAMI.
SO YOU CAN WEAR THE CLOTHES YOU
LOVE AND GET THE COMFORT AND
BEAUTIFUL COVERAGE YOU WANT.
NO MORE EMBARRASSING EXTRA
EXPOSURE IN YOUR V-NECKS.
WITH THE MILANA BRA'