ALEX TREBEK!
THANK YOU, JOHNNY GILBERT.
AND WELCOME,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
AS YOU KNOW, BREAKING THROUGH
THE $100,000 MARK
IN WINNINGS ON "JEOPARDY!"
IS QUITE AN ACCOMPLISHMENT.
AND RIGHT NOW, DAVID
IS LESS THAN $10,000 AWAY
FROM THAT $100,000 MARK.
MARJORIE AND AUSTIN
ARE HERE TO STOP HIM.
GOOD LUCK, PLAYERS.
HERE COMES THE JEOPARDY! ROUND
FOR YOU.
THE CLUES ARE WORTH
FROM $200 TO $1,000
IN THESE CATEGORIES...
ALL RIGHT...
"B-Y" COMING UP
IN EACH CORRECT RESPONSE.
WELL...
DAVID.
LET'S GO WITH CLASSICAL
FOR $200.
UH, WHAT IS THE ORGAN?
NO. AUSTIN.
WHAT IS A VIOLA?
WE'LL TAKE STATE NICKNAMES
FOR $200.
WHAT IS FLORIDA?
$400, STATE NICKNAMES.
WHAT IS ALASKA?
NO. MARJORIE.
WHAT IS COLORADO?
LET'S DO UNOFFICIAL STATE
NICKNAMES FOR $600, PLEASE.
WHAT IS MASSACHUSETTS?
LET'S DO $800 FOR
UNOFFICIAL STATE NICKNAMES.
WHAT IS HAWAII?
$1,000, STATE NICKNAMES.
WHAT IS MARYLAND?
YOU' ON THE PLUS SIDE
WITH $800, TIED WITH AUSTIN.
UH, CLASSICAL MUSIC,
$400.
WHO IS FELIX MENDELSSOHN?
CLASSICAL MUSIC, $600.
WHAT ARE SONGS?
CLASSICAL MUSIC, $800.
LISTEN, AND...
(piano music playing)
UH, WHAT IS
THE "APPASSIONATA"?
UH, CLASSICAL MUSIC, $1,000.
YOU PICKED
THE RIGHT CATEGORY,
BECAUSE THAT HAS
THE DAILY DOUBLE,
AND YOU HAVE THE LEAD.
I'LL RISK $1,000.
$1,000 IT IS.
HERE IS THE CLUE...
WHAT IS THE BAROQUE ERA?
YES.
AND THAT JUMPS YOU
UP TO $3,600.
GO AGAIN.
UH, ONE NIGHT WHEN
I COULDN'T SLEEP... FOR
WHO IS DAVID LETTERMAN?
LET'S DO $400 FOR ONE NIGHT
WHEN I COULDN'T SLEEP... PLEASE.
WHAT IS "MARATHON MAN"?
UH, COULDN'T SLEEP FOR $600.
1:58--TOOK MY DOG
FOR A WALK.
HE'S THIS BREED--
SEE WHY I NAMED HIM
MICHELIN MAN?
WHAT IS A SHAR PEI?
$800, ONE NIGHT
WHEN I COULDN'T SLEEP...
WHAT IS "THE LION KING"?
THAT IS THE MOVIE,
AND THAT TAKES YOU
TO $4,800.
THAT'S A $3,000 LEAD
OVER MARJORIE,
A $4,000 LEAD
OVER AUSTIN.
AND WE'RE TAKING A BREAK.
WELCOME BACK. I MISSPOKE
A FEW MOMENTS AGO.
I SAID, UH, THE FILM,
"THE LION KING,"
AND WE WERE TALKING--
THE CLUE TALKED TO--
TALKED ABOUT THE MUSICAL.
ALL RIGHT. AUSTIN BAIRD
FROM PROVO, UTAH,
GOT ENGAGED
IN AN UNUSUAL WAY.
I DID. I'M LUCKY ENOUGH
TO BE DATING
THE MOST AMAZING GIROW,
AND SHE WAS WILLING TO JUMP
OFF OF A 140-FOOT ARCH,
TAKE AN 80-FOOT DROP,
SWING ABOUT 200 FEET.
UH, WHEN SHE
FINISHED SWINGING,
I REPELLED DOWN TO HER,
WE WERE BOTH ABOUT
20 FEET OFF THE GROUND,
PROPOSED.
AFTER SHE FINISHED
BEING SURPRISED
ANSHED CRYING,
THEN SHE SAID "YES."
THE ONLY WAY
YOU COULD HAVE TOPPED THAT
IS IF YOU HAD JUMPED
AT THE SAME TIME,
AND PROPOSED
ON THE WAY DOWN.
NEXT TIME--OH!
HEY.
LESLIE, I'M KIDDING.
I'M KIDDING.
I DID IT.
ORIE PARKER,
STAY-AT-HOME MOM
FROM AUSTIN, TEXAS,
YES, I HAVE A 1963 CADILLAC
THAT WAS MY VERY FIRST CAR.
IT'S A LONG CAR. IT WOULD
NOT FIT IN MOST GARAGES.
NO, IT'S ACTUALLY LONGER
THAN A CHEVY SUBURBAN.
YEAH.
AND IT TAKES
A LOT OF GAS, TOO.
BUT THAT'S OKAY.
THEY'RE FUN TO HAVE.
YEAH.
DAVID MENCHACA
IS OUR CHAMPION.
BEFORE HE CAME
ON OUR PROGRAM,
HE, UH, PROMISED
HIS FELLOW LAW STUDENTS
THAT IF HE WON,
HE WOULD DO WHAT?
I WOULD, UH, BUY EVERYONE
AT THE VIEWING PARTY A DRINK.
OKAY.
BUT I DIDN'T TELL THEM
WHAT KIND OF DRINK.
(laughte  AND THEY DON'W
WHETHER OR NOT
THEY'RE GETTING IT YET, SO...
YOU'VE WON $91,000
UP TO TODAY.
YOU CAN AFFORD IT.
PICK UP
YOUR SIGNALING DEVICE.
UM, LET'S FINISH
COULDN'T SLEEP FOR $1,000.
WHAT IS ANDORRA?
UM, "BY" FOR $200.
WHAT IS STANDBY?
HOW DO YOU GET "BY"? FOR $400.
WHAT IS A BYPASS?
HOW DO YOU GET "BY"?
FOR $600, PLEASE.
WHAT ARE BYGONES?
HOW DO YOU GET "BY"? FOR $800.
WHAT ARE BYLAWS?
UM, "BY" FOR $1,000.
WHAT IS A PLAY-BY-PLAY?
NO. AUSTIN.
WHAT IS A BLOW-BY-BLOW?
BOXING, YES.
I MANAGE FOR $200.
WHAT IS WATERGATE?
I MANAGE FOR $400, PLEASE.
WHOGI BERRA?
NO.
MARJORIE.
WHO IS TOMMY LASORDA?
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
THE DODGERS, NOT NEW YORK.
I MANAGE FOR $600.
TINKER TO EVERS
TO CHANCE. FRANK CHANCE.
MARJORIE, BACK TO YOU.
I MANAGE FOR $800, PLEASE.
EXCITING MOMENTS
MFOR CANADIANS.TO YOU.
THE TORONTO BLUE JAYS
WAS THE TEAM.
MARJORIE, GO AGAIN.
I MANAGE FOR $1,000.
WHO IS DAVID JUSTICE?
NO. AUSTIN OR DAVID?
WHO IS BOBBY COX?
LESS THAN A MINUTE
TO GO NOW, MARJORIE.
LET'S DO HERSHEY'S
FOR $200, PLEASE.
WHAT ARE NUTS?
MORE SPECIFIC? MORE SPECIFIC?
WHAT ARE ALMONDS?
$400.
WHAT IS PHILADELPHIA?
$600.
WHAT IS POT OF GOLD?
$800.
WHAT ARE TWIZZLERS?
NOW THE LAST CLUE...
WHAT ARE REESE'S?
AND THAT TAKES YOU UP
TO $3,200,
AND,N, YOU WILL
BE SELECTING FIRST
IN DOUBLE JEOPARDY!
WHEN WE COME BACK AFTER THIS.
CLOSED CAPTIONING
SPONSORED IN PART BY...
TIME FOR DOUBLE JEOPARDY!
AUSTIN IS READY,
SO LET'S SHOW HIM
THE CATEGORIES
FOR THIS ROUND OF PLAY.
WE START WITH...
HISTORY THERE...
YOU GITHE FILM....
AND FINALLY, CLUES FROM...
AUSTIN, YOU START.
LEAGUE OF NATIONS
FOR $400, PLEASE.
WHAT IS PARIS?
UM, 1-WORD FILM QUOTES
FOR $400.
WHAT IS
"FERRIS BUELLER'S DAY OFF"?
UH, 1-WORD FILM QUOTES
FOR $800.
WHAT IS "STAR TREK 2:
THE WRATH OF KHAN"?
UH, FILM QUOTES FOR $1,200.
WHAT IS "ANIMAL HOUSE"?
LEAGUE OF NATIONS, $800.
WHAT IS SECRETARY-GENERAL??
LET'S DO, UH, 1-WORD FILM QUOTES
FOR $1,600, PLEASE.
WHAT IS "DOG DAY AFTERNOON"?
UH, FILM QUOTES FOR $2,000.
WH"RED DAWN"?
FOR $2,000.
LEAGUE OF NATIONS FOR $1,600.
WHAT IS CHOLERA?
NO.
HANSEN'S DISEASE
IS LEPROSY.
AUSTIN, BACK TO YOU.
LEAGUE OF NATIONS, $1,200.
WHAT IS NORWAY?
NO. AUSTIN OR DAVID?
THE OTHER COUNTRY
WAS FINLAND.
AUSTCK TO YOU.
LET'S FINISH IT OFF
FOR $2,000.
WHAT IS THE JORDAN?
WE'RE IN
THE MIDDLE EAST.
WE'LL DO ZEUS YOUR DADDY
FOR $400, PLEASE.
WHO IS APHRODITE?
$800, ZEUS YOUR
WHO IS HERMES?
UH, ZEUS YOUR DADDY
FOR $1,200.
I'LL BET $2,500.
OKAY. HERE'S THE CLUE...
DAVID?
WHO ARE CASTOR AND POLLUX?
YES. YOU PICKED
THE RIGHT TWO.
GO AGAIN.
UH, ZEUS FOR $1,600.
WHO IS ATHENA?
UH, ZEUS FOR $2,000.
WHO IS PERSEUS?
THAT'S ANOTHER $2,000
AS YOU ADD TO YOUR LEAD.
UH, BIT OF BRIT LITFOR $4.
WHO IS AUSTEN?
NO. MARJORIE.
WHO IS BLON--BRONTE?
ELIZABETH...
ELIZABETH BRONTE.
NO. DAVID.
WHO IS EMILY BRONTE?
NO. CORRECT RESPONSE--
WHO WAS CHARLOTTE BRONTE?
DAVID, BACK TO YOU.
BRIT LIT FOR $800.
WHO IS JANE AUSTEN?
UH, BRIT LIT FOR $1,200.
UM, BRIT LIT, $1,600.
WHAT IS COLLINS?
UH, BRIT LIT FOR $2,000.
AND HE IS THE VENERABLE BEDE.
B-E-D-E.
DAVID.
UM, MICHELLE OBAMA FOR $400.
ALL RIGHT...
WHO IS BIDEN?
JILL BIDEN.
COMPLETE THE ANIMAL PHRASE
FOR $1,200, PLEASE.
WHAT IS A CAT?
$1,600, PLEASE.
ONE SWALLOW DOES NOT
MAKE A WHOLE SUMMER. AUSTIN?
ANIMAL PHRASE FOR $2,000.
SWALLOW A CAMEL.
HARD TO DO. AUSTIN.
COMPLETE THE ANIMAL PHRASE
FOR $800.
WHAT IS GRAY MARE?
UM, MICHELLE OBAMA FOR $800.
ALL RIGHT...
WHAT IS THE PEOPLE'S HOUSE?
LET'S DO $1,200, PLEASE,
FOR FIRST LADY.
LET'S MAKE IT
A TRUE DAILY DOUBLE.
ALL RIGHT. FOR $3,200,
HERE IS THE CLUE...
SAY SOMETHING.
MARTIN LUTHER KING'S SPEECH
ON THE WASHINGTON MONUMENT?
OR...
OH, GOSH.
(beep)
"I HAVE A DREAM."
THAT'S--
THE "I HAVE A DREAM"
SPEECH.
YOU WERE SO CLOSE. SORRY,
WE CAN'T GIVE IT TO YOU, THOUGH.
PICK.
LET'S DO $1,600,
FIRST LADY, PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT...
AT IS
A PORTUGUESE WATER DOG?
$2,000, PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT...
WHAT IS AmeriCorps?
AND NOW THE LAST CLUE
IN COMPLETE THE ANIMAL PHRASE...
WHAT ARE MICE?
AND WITH THAT,
YOU GO TO $23,200.
MARJORIE HAS NO MONEY, SO WE
HAVE TO SAY GOOD-BYE TO HER.
AUSTIN AND DINAL,
AND BEFORE WE
REVEAL THE CATEGORY,
I DO WANT TO THANK, ON BEHALF OF
ALL OF US HERE AT "JEOPARDY!",
THE FIRST LADY MICHELLE OBAMA.
IT'S NOT VERY OFTEN
YOU GET A FIRST LADY
TO DO CLUES FOR "JEOPARDY!"
AND TO DO THEM SO WELL.
FINAL JEOPARDY! CATEGORY,
PLAYERS--
2011 MUSICMAKERS.
WE'RE BACK IN A MOMENT.
HI VICTOR!
MOM?
I KNOW YOU GOT TO GO
IN A MINUTE
BUT THIS IS
A REAL QUICK MEAL,
THAT'S PERFECT FOR TWO!
CAMPBELL'S CHUNKY BEEF
WITH COUNGETABLES,
POURED OVER RICE!
[ Male Announcer ]
CAMPBELLRIGHT.
IT FILLS YOU UP RIGHT.
POURED OVER RICE!
TRY VE Male Announcer ]
CAMPBELLRIGHT.
of Washington about the future
of Medicare and Social Security.
ANNCR: B deserve straight
talk about the options on the...
table and what they mean for you
and your family.
ANCR: AARP is cutting through
all the political spin.ut yu
Because for our 37 million
members, only one word counts.
Get the facts at earnedasay.org.
Let's keep Medicare...
and Social Security strong for
generations to come.
CAN YOUR MOISTURIZER DO THAT?
[ Female Announcer ]
DERMATOLOGIST RECOMMENDED
Aveeno HAS AN OAT FORMULA,
SO SKIN CAN REPLENISH ITSELF.
THAT'S HEALTHY SKIN FOR LIFE.
ONLY FROM Aveeno.
TOMATO,
OBVIOUSLY.
HAHA. THERE'S MOR ,
THERE'S A KICK TO IT.
WAHLALALALALLALA!
SMOOTH, BUT CRISP.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE DRINKING
A FOOD THAT'S A DRINK,
OR A DRINK THAT'S A FOOD,
WOOOOOH!
[ Male Announcer ] TASTE IT
AND DESCRIBE THE INDESCRIBABLE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
WE'LL BE BACK
WITH FINAL JEOPARDY!
RIGHT AFTER THIS.
2011 MUSICMAKERS
IS THE CATEGORY,
AND THIS IS THE CLUE...
30 SECONDS, GENTLEMEN.
GOOD LUCK.
♪
YOU GUYS WROTE
YOUR RESPONSES DOWN QUICKLY.
I THINK THAT MEANS
GOOD NEWS.
AUSTIN,
WE START WITH YOU.
WHICH TWO SINGERS
DICOME UP WITH?
YOU WROTE DOWN
ADELE AND RIHANNA.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
AND YOU WILL ADD...
$5,500. YOU GO TO $16,500.
DAVID COULDN'T
BE CAUGHT, THOUGH.
HE HAD $23,300.
DID HE COME UP
WITH ADELE AND RIHANNA?
YES, HE DID.
AND HE WILL ADD
HOW MUCH?
$700 ONLY.
THAT TAKES HIM
TO $24,000 TODAY,
AND NOW PUTS HIM OVER
THE $100,000 MARK.
$115,503. AND HE GETS
TO PLAY AGAIN TOMORROW.
SEE YOU THEN.
PROMOTIONAL CONSIDERATION
PROVIDED BY...
WHEEL...
OF...
FORTUNE!
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
PAT SAJAK ANA WHITE!
OH, THANK YOU, JIM.
THANK YOU, EVERYBODY.
THANK YOU, RED.
[ LAUGHS ]
THANKS.
APPRECIATE THAT.
SEE YOU LATER.
YES.
[ LAUGHS ]
OH. HI!
HI.