SAM: DOLPHINS LIKE
CRUNCH HERE ARE PLAYFUL
AND INTELLIGENT ANIMALS,
BUT THEY DO HAVE COMPLEX
SOCIAL STRUCTURES,
INCLUDING SOMETHING
CALLED MALE COALITIONS.
THAT'S WHEN TWO MALE
DOLPHINS FORM A
LONG-LASTING BOND.
IN THIS SEA RESCUE, A
DOLPHIN TURNS UP
SEVERELY INJURED ON
FLORIDA'S ATLANTIC
COAST, AND THAT BOND
BETWEEN TWO DOLPHINS IS
ABOUT TO BE PUT TO THE
TEST.
IT'S A SWELTERING AUGUST
DAY IN VERO BEACH,
FLORIDA.
OUR RESCUE TEAM RESPONDS
TO A CALL OF A DOLPHIN
IN DISTRESS.
IT SOUNDS LIKE A
STRAIGHTFORWARD CASE,
BUT NONE OF THEM HAVE
ANY IDEA THEY'RE ABOUT
TO MEET AN ANIMAL THAT
WILL TEACH THEM A
LIFE-CHANGING LESSON.
JON: ABOUT MID-DAY, WE
GOT A PHONE CALL ABOUT A
DOLPHIN THAT WAS OVER IN
INDIAN RIVER THAT
SOUNDED LIKE A BOAT
STRIKE.
SAM: A BADLY-INJURED
DOLPHIN HAS BEACHED
HIMSELF IN A WARM-WATER
INLET.
IT'S FAR AWAY FROM OPEN
WATERS DOLPHINS NORMALLY
CALL HOME.
JON: WE PUT A CREW
TOGETHER HERE AT
SEAWORLD, GOT READY, AND
HEADED OVER TO INDIAN
RIVER TO SEE WHAT
ACTUALLY WAS GOING ON
WITH THIS DOLPHIN.
SAM: SEAWORLD ASSEMBLES
TWO TEAMS TO HELP RESCUE
THE DOLPHIN: ONE FROM
SEAWORLD ORLANDO, THE
OTHER FROM HARBOR BRANCH
OCEANOGRAPHIC INSTITUTE,
A RESEARCH ORGANIZATION
FROM FLORIDA ATLANTIC
UNIVERSITY.
MAN: WE CAN USE SOME
ROPE, TOO.
MAN: OKAY, WE SHOULD BE
THERE IN LESS THAN FIVE.
SAM: RESCUERS RACE TO
THE SPOT WHERE THE
DOLPHIN WAS LAST SEEN.
JON: WHEN THE SEAWORLD
RESCUE TEAM GOT TO THE
BOAT RAMP, THE ANIMAL
WAS GONE.
IT HAD ALREADY SWAM OFF.SAMD
SAM: THEY FIND A POD OF
DOLPHINS IN THE LAGOON,
BUT THEY DON'T SEE AN
INJURED ONE.
WOMAN: CALF OVER HERE.
YEAH, BEHIND YOU.
JON: WE HAD BOATS GOING
A LITTLE BIT OF
EVERYWHERE LOOKING.
AFTER A LITTLE BIT OF
TIME, WE ACTUALLY FOUND
THE ANIMAL.
AT THIS POINT, IT WAS
TIME TO TRY TO RESCUE
IT.
SAM: THEY SET NETS, BUT
EVEN THOUGH THIS DOLPHIN
IS SERIOUSLY INJURED,
HE'S STILL ABLE TO
OUT-SWIM THE RESCUE
EFFORTS OVER AND OVER
AGAIN.
WOMAN: OH, HE'S OUT!
JON: YOU CIRCLE THE
ANIMAL WITH THE BOAT AND
TRY TO PUT A NET AROUND
IT, AND EVERY TIME WE
DID, THE DOL
SHOW UP OUTSIDE THE NET.
HE'D EITHER SWIM UNDER
IT, HE'D SWIM AROUND IT,
HE'D BE FASTER THAN US;
AND FOR AN ANIMAL THAT'S
INJURED TO BE FASTER
THAN OUR BOATS, IT'S NOT.
SAM: RESCUERS ARE NO
CLOSER TO SAVING OUR
DOLPHIN, AND NOW IT'S
GETTING DARK.
THAT MAKES THE RESCUE
EFFORT DANGEROUS.
THEY MAKE THE DIFFICULT
DECISION TO RETURN TO
LAND, WAITING FOR
DAYBREAK, BUT THERE IS
NO GUARANTEE THE DOLPHIN
WILL SURVIVE THE NIGHT.
JON: AS WE WERE DRIVING
BACK, THE DOLPHIN POPPED
UP RIGHT NEXT TO THE
BOAT, RIGHT OFF THE
FRONT OF THE BOAT, AND
IT WAS JUST A PERFECT
OPPORTUNITY.
SAM: RESCUERS JUMP IN TO
HELP CORRAL THE DOLPHIN
INTO THE NET.
NOW THEY FACE A NEW SET
JON: WE'VE GOT SHARKS,
WE'VE GOT STINGRAYS,
WE'VE GOT DEEP WATER,
CURRENTS, OTHER BOATS
THAT ARE COMING AROUND.
SO, AS SOON AS WE GET IN
THE WATER, WE WANT TO
WORK VERY SAFELY, BUT WE
WANT TO WORK VERY
QUICKLY TO GET THAT
ANIMAL IN HAND AND GET
HIM BACK ON THE BACK OF
THE BOAT.
SAM: OUR DOLPHIN IS
FINALLY IN THE NET, BUT
RESCUERS HAVE TO MAKE NOT EE
SURE HE DOES NOT ESCAPE
UNDER THE BOAT, SO THEY
TAP THE WATER.
IT'S A TECHNIQUE THEY
USE TRYING TO KEEP HIM
WHERE HE NEEDS TO BE.
MAN: HEY, WHAT WE'RE
GOING TO HAVE TO DO IS
GET HIM IN THE
STRETCHER, AND GET HIM
UP, AND THEN GET THE NET
OFF TO THE SIDE.
MAN: YEAH, WE CAN DO
THAT.
SAM: WITH SOLID
TEAMWORK, THEY PULL THE
INJURED DOLPHIN ABOARD.
MAN: ON THREE.
ONE, TWO, THREE, GO.
ONE MORE.
I'VE GOT SOME WATER.
ONE MORE TIME, TWO,
THREE.
WATCH HIS FLUKE.
SAM: AND ARE SHOCKED BY
WHAT THEY SEE.
JON: WE FOUND OUT IT
WASN'T A BOAT STRIKE AT
ALL.
IT WAS ACTUALLY A SHARK
BITE RIGHT DOWN THE
CENTER OF HIS BACK.
DR. DOLD: SHARK BITES
FOR ANY ANIMAL,
SPECIFICALLY BOTTLENOSE
DOLPHINS, ARE A SERIOUS
INJURY AND NOTHING TO BE
TAKEN LIGHTLY.
REMEMBER, WHEN SHARKS
REMEMBER
BITE, THEY CAUSE A LOT
OF TISSUE DAMAGE.
IN ALL THE TIME I'VE
WORKED AT SEAWORLD AND
RESCUED ANIMALS, I'VE
NEVER SEEN A WOUND THAT
WAS THIS LARGE MADE BY
ANOTHER ANIMAL.
IT'S PHENOMENAL THAT THE
ANIMAL IS STILL ALIVE.
SAM: HIS WOUNDS ARE SO
SEVERE, OUR DOLPHIN
COULD GO INTO SHOCK
DURING TRANSPORT.
RESCUERS RACE THE
CRITICALLY INJURED
ANIMAL TO HARBOR
BRANCH'S CARE FACILITY.
MAN: EASY, PASS OFF.
SAM: WHEN HE ARRIVES AT
HARBOR BRANCH, PROGRAM
MANAGER STEVE MCCULLOCH
MAKES ANOTHER STARTLING
DISCOVERY.
STEVE: BASED ON THE
DESCRIPTION OF THE
DOLPHIN'S MARKINGS ON
HIS FINS, WE KNEW IT WAS
C6.
SAM: THIS DOLPHIN FIRST
CAME INTO CONTACT WITH
RESEARCHERS 20 YEARS
AGO, AND THAT'S WHEN
THEY NAMED HIM C6.
TWO DECADES LATER, HE'S
IN URGENT NEED OF HELP.
COMING UP, CAN C6
SURVIVE A BRUTAL SHARK
ATTACK?ESCUERS
AND THEN RESCUERS
DISCOVER OUR DOLPHIN HAS
A CLOSE FRIEND AND LEARN
NOTHING WILL KEEP THESE
TWO APART.
WE SET SAIL
ABOARD SeaWorld ONE
TO ENCOUNTER FANTASTICAL
SEA CREATURES AND STUFF,
WHEN SUDDENLY...
SHAMU OF THE SEA RISES AND
THE OCEAN CRASHES OVER THE BOW
WHEN OUR SONAR DETECTED
A TURTLE WORLD.
SO I TOOK CONTROL
AND STEERED US THROUGH IT.
THEN A CURIOUS SEA CREATURE
APPROACHED, AND AS OUR EYES MET
WE WERE TRANSPORTED
TO A SUPER-SECRET
UNDERWATER CAVERN...
I THINK THEY LIKED
THEN A CURIOSeaWorld?EATURE
APPROI THINK THEY LIKED IT. MET
[ Female Announcer ]
START YOUR ADVENTURES TODAY
AT Seaworld.com
AND FIND SPECIAL OFFERS.
♪
This holiday when Kmart
Shop Your Way members
check out, they
can win...
... a trip to
Universal Orlando Resort,
during our 30 Days of
Surprise Sweepstakes.
You could have a despicably
good time.
Fly with Harry.
Or win lots of other
great prizes.
For more chances to win visit
Shop Your Way .com
Only at Kmart.
TO FLAT SCREENS...NS...
TWIZZLERIZE YOUR
ENTERTAINMENT EVERYDAY
WITH TWIZZLERS,
THE TWIST YOU CAN'T RESIST.
[ Female Announcer ]
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA BARS,
RICH DARK CHOCOLATE,
TOASTED OATS.
PERFECT COMBINATIONS OF
NATURE'S DELICIOUS INGREDIENTS,
FROM NATURE VALLEY.
♪
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA BARS,
NATURE AT ITS MOST DELICIOUS.
YOU SPEND ALL DAY COOKING IT.
SO WHY SPEND EVEN A MOMENT
CONSIDERING ANY BROTH
BUT SWANSON?
THE BROTH COOKS TRUST MOST
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
IN STUFFING AND MORE,
THE SECRET IS SWANSON.
TO MAKE THE MEshe doesn't ND
Even though our really get us.
And she'll never know
who we are, or what...
No way,
Madden Girls??
Nike!
Who's your mommy now?
Famous brands. Famously easy.
Famous Footwear.
Victory is Yours.
SAM: IN VERO BEACH,
FLORIDA, A SEVERELY
INJURED DOLPHIN BEACHES
HIMSELF AND IS IN
DESPERATE NEED OF HELP.
SEAWORLD RESCUERS SAVE
HIM AND RUSH TO FLORIDA
ATLANTIC UNIVERSITY'S
HARBOR BRANCH INSTITUTE
IN FORT PIERCE, FLORIDA.
STAFF THERE MAKE AN
INCREDIBLE DISCOVERY.
THEY ALREADY KNOW THIS
DOLPHIN.
STEVE: C6 AND ANOTHER
DOLPHIN, IDENTIFIED AS
C7, WERE PART OFA
POPULATION STUDY IN 1980
AND 1981.
THEY WERE BOTH FREEZE
BRANDED C6 AND C7, THE
MARKS VISIBLE ON THEIR
DORSAL FINS TO HELP
SCIENTISTS IDENTIFY THE
DOLPHINS IN A POPULATION
STUDY.
SAM: WHEN RESEARCHERS
FIRST IDENTIFIED C6 AND
HIS FRIEND C7, IT WAS
1980, AND THEY WERE JUST
FIVE YEARS OLD.
THEY ALSO NOTICED THE
PAIR WERE INSEPARABLE.
THIS STRONG BOND BETWEEN
MALE DOLPHINS IS KNOWN
AS A MALE COALITION OR
BACHELOR POD.
DR. DOLD: AS YOUNG MALES
GROW UP, THEY LEAVE
THEIR MATERNAL GROUP AND
FORM THESE MALE
COALITIONS.
THERE'S ALSO SAFETY IN
NUMBERS, AND SO TO BE
PART OF A SOCIAL GROUP,
IT HELPS YOUR CHANCES OF
SUCCESS FOR GROWING, AND
BREEDING, AND BEING AN
SOTIVE PART OF A DOLPHIN
SOCIETY.
SAM: JUST LIKE HUMANS,
THE DOLPHIN WORLD IS
FULL OF COMPLE
FULL OF COMPLEX SOCIAL
DYNAMICS.
THEY FORM CLOSE FRIENDLY
BONDS, PAIR OFF TO MATE,
AND EVEN DEVELOP
RIVALRIES, AND SOMETIMES
THOSE DOLPHIN RIVALRIES
CAN ESCALATE TO
BULLYING.
A STORY STRAIGHT FROM
THE HEADLINES.
OFF HUNTINGTON BEACH,
CALIFORNIA, A GANG OF
DOLPHINS TARGET FREDDY,
CHASING HIM OUT OF THE
OCEAN AND INTO SHALLOW
BRACKISH WATER.
EACH TIME FREDDY TRIES
TO RETURN TO DEEPER
WATERS, THE GROUP FORCES
HIM BACK TOWARD SHORE.
EXPERTS AREN'T SURE WHAT
CAUSES THIS BEHAVIOR IN
DOLPHINS, BUT DOMINANCE
IS COMMON IN DOLPHIN
RELATIONSHIPS.
DR. DOLD: THE DARKER
SIDE TO THESE GROUPS OF
MALES IS ALL CENTERED ON
COMPETITION,
PARTICULARLY AROUND
TIMES WHERE BREEDING IS
IMPORTANT, AND THIS
COMPETITION IN DOLPHINS
CAN ACTUALLY TURN QUITE
AGGRESSIVE; AND AT TIMES
LIKE THAT, YOU GET THE
MALES SEPARATING FROM
EACH OTHER.
SAM: BUT THERE WAS NO
SEPARATING C6 AND C7.
THEIR BOND IS ONE OF THE
STRONGEST RESEARCHERS
HAVE EVER SEEN.
IN 1981, A YEAR AFTER
RESEARCHERS TAGGED C6
AND C7, THE PAIR WAS
SPOTTED TOGETHER, AND IN
1997 THEY WERE SPOTTED
AGAIN MAKING THIS BOND
ONE OF THE
LONGEST-LASTING IN
HISTORY.
STEVE: C6 AND C7 ARE THE
LONGEST KNOWN DOCUMENTED
MALE COALITION PAIR THAT
WE KNOW OF; AND IN TERMS
OF MALE COALITIONS, THIS
IS IMPORTANT, BECAUSE
THEY'RE SPREADING STRONGNETS
ESSENTIAL TO THE
SURVIVAL OF THE INDIAN
RIVER LAGOON POPULATION.
SAM: EVEN WITH THE
MUTUAL SUPPORT THE MALE
COALITION PROVIDES OUR
DOLPHINS, IT'S NOT
ENOUGH TO PREVENT
ATTACKS BY PREDATORS.
BULL SHARKS ARE
AGGRESSIVE HUNTERS FOUND
IN SHALLOW COASTAL
WATERS AND INLETS.
DR. DOLD: BULL SHARKS,
KNOWN TO BE FAIRLY
AGGRESSIVE SPECIES OF
SHARK -- IN FACT, IT'S
THE COMMON SPECIES WE
HEAR OF WHEN WE THINK OF
PEOPLE GETTING BIT BY
SHARKS ON THE BEACH --
ARE NOT VERY
DISCRIMINATING.
THEY WILL SORT OF BITE
AT ANYTHING, WHETHER TO
TEST IT, EXPLORE IT, OR
ULTIMATELY TO EAT IT.
SAM: THE BULL SHARK IS A
RELENTLESS PREDATOR.
THEY'RE FAST, FEARSOME,
AND THEY SHARE THE SAME
WATERS AS THE BOTTLENOSE
DOLPHIN.
STEVE AND HIS TEAM
EXAMINE C6'S WOUNDS AND
CONCLUDE HE WAS ATTACKED
NOT BY ONE BULL SHARK,
BUT BY FOUR OF THEM.
MAN: THERE'S CUTS THAT
INDICATES THAT IT'S A
BULL SHARK.
STEVE: C6 HAD EXTENSIVE
INJURIES OVER HIS ENTIRE
BODY FROM BULL SHARKS.
IT WAS DETERMINED THERE
WERE FOUR DIFFERENT
SHARKS RANGING IN SIZE
FROM APPROXIMATELY FOUR
FEET TO OVER NINE FEET
IN LENGTH, AND THE
INJURIES WERE VERY
SEVERE AND NEAR FATAL.
SAM: RESCUERS TREAT C6'S
WOUNDS AS SOON AS HE
ARRIVES AT THE HARBOR
BRANCH FACILITY.
STEVE: HIS BLOOD
CHEMISTRY, IN FACT, WAS
NOT REALLY COMPATIBLE
WITH SIGNS OF LIFE.
SO, HE WAS IN A VERY
GRAVE STATE.
SAM: THE ORANGE AND
WHITE COLOR OF SOME OF
THE GASHES SHOW C6'S
WOUNDS ARE OLD, AND THE
TISSUE IS DYING.
HE NEEDS ANTIBIOTICS
IMMEDIATELY.
MAN: HAVE YOU GOT ANY
TRIPLE ANTIBIOTIC?
MAN: HUH, TRIPLE
ANTIBIOTIC OINTMENT?
MAN: DO WE HAVE ANY
TRIPLE ANTIBIOTIC?
STEVE: HE WAS A VERY
PATIENT, PATIENT,
ALLOWING US TO DO OUR
JOB, WHICH WAS REMOVING
HIM FROM THE POOL
SEVERAL TIMES DAILY TO
TREAT THESE INJURIES.
SAM: C6 IS LOWERED INTO
A SMALL POOL FOR
OBSERVATION AND DOES NOT
REACT WELL TO HIS NEW
ENVIRONMENT.
EXPERTS ARE CONCERNED BY
THE DOLPHIN'S
APPEARANCE.
WHILE C6'S
LIFE-THREATENING
INJURIES ARE THE FIRST
PRIORITY, THEY ARE NOT
HIS ONLY ISSUES.
STEVE: HE HAD CATARACT
IN ONE OF HIS EYES.
HE HAD SOME LIGHT
SCOLIOSIS TO HIS TAIL
FLUKE REGION; AND,
OVERALL, HE WAS JUST AN
OLDER MALE DOLPHIN.
SAM: COMING UP, ON HIS
LONG ROAD TO RECOVERY,
C6 WINS THE HEARTS OF
ALL THOSE AROUND HIM.
MAN: GOOD BOY!
SAM: AND THEY'RE ABOUT
TO BE AMAZED WHEN HE
RECEIVES AN UNEXPECTED
VISITOR.
For months, I had this deep pain
all over my body.
away.
My doctor diagnosed it
as fibromyalgia,
thought to be the
result of overactive nerves
that causead pain.
Lyrica is believed
to calm these nerves.
I learned Lyrica can provide
significant relief
from fibromyalgia pain.
And for some people,
it can work in as early as
the first week of treatment.
So now I can plan my days
and accomplish more.
Lyrica is not for everyone.
Lyrica may cause serious
allergic reactions
or suicidal thoughts or actions.
Tell your doctor right away
if you have these,
new or worsening depression,
or unusual changes in mood
or behavior,
or any swelling or
affected breathing or skin,
or changes in eyesight,
including blurry vision
or muscle pain with fever
or tired feeling.
Common side effects
are dizziness, sleepiness,
weight gain, and swelling of
hands, legs and feet.
Don't drink alcohol
while taking Lyrica.
Don't drive or use machinery
until you know
how Lyrica affects you.
With less pain,
I'm feeling better
now that I've found Lyrica.
Ask your doctor
if Lyrica is right
for your fibromyalgia pain.
PREGO?!
BUT I'VE BOUGHT RAGU FOR YEARS.
[ Thinking ] WONDER WHAT OTHER
QUESTIONABLE CHOICES I'VE MADE?
I CHOOSE DATE NUMBER 2!
WHOOO!
[ sigh of relief ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHOOSE TASTE. CHOOSE PREGO.
[ sigh of relief ]
I NEED YOU.
I FEEL SO ALONE.
BUT YOU'RE NOT
ALONE.
I KNEW YOU'D COME.
LIKE I COULD STAY AWAY.
YOU KNOW I CAN'T DO THIS
WITHOUT YOU.
YOU'LL NEVER HAVE TO.
YOU'RE ALWAYS THERE
FOR ME.
SHH!
I'LL GET YOU
A RENTAL CAR.
I COULD ALSO USE
AN UMBRELLA.
FALL IN LOVE WITH
PROGRESSIVE'S CLAIMS SERVICE.
with hand-layered pasta,
tomatoes,
and real mozzarella cheese.
But what makes us even
prouder...
is what our real
dinners can do for your family.
Stouffer's.
Let's fix dinner.
[ Female Announcer ]
HOLIDAY COOKIES ARE A BIG JOB.
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE
JUST RIGHT.
PERFECTION IS IN THE DETAILS.
♪
GET TO HOLIDAY FUN FASTER
WITH PILLSBURY COOKIE DOUGH.
SAM: C6, AN AGING
DOLPHIN, FACES AN UPHILL
RECOVERY AFTER BEING
MAULED BY FOUR BULL
SHARKS.
AS HE MAKES THAT SLOW
BUT DETERMINED PROGRESS,
EVEN SEASONED RESCUERS
ARE AMAZED AT JUST HOW
STRONG THE BONDS BETWEENAN .
TWO DOLPHINS CAN BE.
STEVE: THE INJURIES THAT
C6 SUSTAINED FROM THERE NEAR
SHARK ATTACKS WERE NEAR
FATAL, COVERING ABOUT
40% OF HIS BODY.
SAM: DESPITE HIS
CONDITION, THE DEDICATED
TEAM WILL NOT GIVE UP ON
THIS ANIMAL.
MAN: GOOD BOY.
GOOD BOY!
SAM: STEVE DEVOTES HIS
DAYS AND NIGHTS TO THE
RECOVERY OF C6, SLEEPING
AT THE CARE FACILITY
EVERY NIGHT FOR SIX
MONTHS TO KEEP WATCH
OVER THIS SPECIAL
DOLPHIN.
STEVE: WHEN YOU'RE
WORKING WITH A DOLPHIN
LIKE C6, YOU ALMOST WANTTO E
DOLPHIN ACTUALLY KNOWS
THAT YOU'RE TRYING TO
HELP HIM.
SAM: PROGRESS IS SLOW AT
FIRST, BUT C6 BEGINS
EATING MORE, FUELING HIS
RECOVERY.
IN JUST A FEW MONTHS,
HIS WOUNDS ARE HEALING.
HE'S GOT MORE ENERGY,
BUT HE HAS ONE BIZARRE
HABIT.
STEVE: WE NOTICED A
UNIQUE TRAIT THAT THIS
PARTICULAR DOLPHIN
DISPLAYED, ONE THAT I'D
NEVER SEEN BEFORE IN 40
YEARS.
C6 WOULD ACTUALLY SINK
AND LAY ON HIS SIDE ON
THE BOTTOM OF THE POOL,
ALMOST GIVING THE
APPEARANCE THAT HE HAD
DROWNED.
MAN: THAT'S HOW HE
RESTS.
STEVE: WHEN WE FIRST
OBSERVED IT, IT WAS
QUITE A START.
WE ACTUALLY JUMPED IN
THE POOL TO INTERVENE.
DR. DOLD: EVERY ONCE IN
A WHILE, THEY'LL THROW
YOU A CURVE.
THIS WAS A NICE REMINDER
OF THE FACT THAT
BEHAVIORS WE DON'T
COMMONLY SEE ARE NOT
ALWAYS INDICATIVE OFA
LARGER PROBLEM.
SAM: THANKFULLY, C6 IS
ONLY PLAYING WHEN HE'S
PLAYING DEAD.
OUR DOLPHIN IS ACTUALLY
BECOMING LIVELIER BY THE
DAY.
STEVE: HE REQUIRED LESS
MEDICAL TREATMENT, AND
HE BECAME STRONGER.
LIFE IN THE WILD ISN'T
EASY, AND C6 NEEDED TO
BE IN TOP SHAPE.
SAM: THE RESCUE TEAM
MOVES HIM TO A LARGER
POOL THAT OVERLOOKS THE
LAGOON, AND HERE THE
STORY OF C6 TAKES
ANOTHER AMAZING TURN.
STEVE: C6 WOULD BECOME
HIGHLY ANIMATED,
VOCALIZING, FAST
SWIMMING, SPY HOPPING.
SO, WE LOOKED FOR SOME
TYPE OF STIMULUS THAT
INFLUENCING THAT
BEHAVIOR.
SAM: THEY LOOK OUT JUST
BEYOND THE POOL AND INTO
THE LAGOON.
STEVE: WE COULD HEAR A
DOLPHIN'S BLOWHOLE
BREATHING.
WE CONFIRMED THAT IT WAS
NOT JUST ANY DOLPHIN.IT WAS.
SAM: AFTER SIX WEEKS, C7
HAS FINALLY LOCATED HIS
LOST COMPANION, C6, AND
IT'S MORE THAN TEN MILES
AWAY FROM WHERE THEY
LAST SAW EACH OTHER.
STEVE: IT'S A VERY
EXCITING TIME TO
ACTUALLY SEE THAT THESE
TWO DOLPHINS HAVE A
STRONGER CONNECTION THAN
MAYBE WE'RE AWARE OF,
THAT THE DOLPHINS COULD
ACTUALLY COMMUNICATE IN
OWN LANGUAGE TOREQUENCIES IN
MAKE CONTACT WITH ONE
ANOTHER.
DR. DOLD: DOLPHIN
COMMUNICATION AND
DOLPHINS LOCATING EACH
OTHER OVER DISTANCE IS
SOMETHING WE CONTINUE TO
LEARN MORE ABOUT.
DOLPHINS CAN ECHOLOCATE.
THEY HAVE SIGNATURE
WHISTLES, WHISTLES THAT
ARE SPECIFIC TO
INDIVIDUAL ANIMALS, AND
PRESUMABLY LOCATE EACH
OTHER WHEN THERE'S NO
VISUAL CONTACT
WHATSOEVER.
SAM: IT'S BE
SAM: IT'S BEEN EIGHT
MONTHS OF INTENSE
REHABILITATION.
NOW C6 SEEMS TO BE READY
TO RETURN HOME AND BE
REUNITED WITH HIS FRIEND
C7, WHO'S WAITING
NEARBY.
STEVE: C6 WAS A POWERFUL
ANIMAL, AND HE HAD
CONSISTENTLY
DEMONSTRATED HIS ABILITY
TO CAPTURE LIVE FOOD IN
THE POOL.
HE WAS ALSO OFF
ANTIBIOTICS.
MAN: GOOD BOY.
STEVE: C6 WAS READY FOR
HIS RETURN HOME.
SAM: COMING UP, C6 IS
READY FOR HIS RETURN,
BUT CAN THIS AGING
DOLPHIN SURVIVE IN THE
WILD?
[ Boy 1 ] Hey!
That's the last Crescent.
Oh, did you want it?
Yea
We'll split it.
[ Female Announcer ]
Made fresh, so light,
Yea
We'll split it.
That's half
That's not half!
Guys, I have more!
Thanks Mom
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Crescents.
Let the Making Begin
[ ding! ]
LOSING YOUR CHEX MIX TOO EASILY?
TIME TO DEPLOY
THE BORING-POTATO CHIP
DECOY BAG.
THEN NO ONE WILL WANT TO STEAL
THE DELICIOUSNESS.
[ Male Announcer ] WITH A
VARIETY OF TASTES AND TEXTURES,
ONLY CHEX MIX
IS A BAG OF INTERESTING.
[ Male Announcer ] WITH A
VARIETY OF TASTES AND TEXTURES,
OH, IT'S GREAT!
NOW I CAN BREW MY COFFEE
JUST THE WAY I LOVE IT.
HOW DO YOU DO THAT?
WELL, INSIDE THE BREWER,
THERE'S THIS TRAIN
THAT'S POWERFUL ENOUGH
TO CARRY MORE COFFEE
AND FRESH WATER TO MAKE COFFEE
THAT'S STRONGER
AND BIGGER...
AND EVEN HOTTER!
ACTUALLY, I JUST PRESS
THIS BUTTON.
BREW THE COFFEE YOU LOVE --
STRONGER, BIGGER, OR HOTTER --
WITH THE KEURIG VUE.
TO FLAT SCREENS...NS...
TWIZZLERIZE YOUR
ENTERTAINMENT EVERYDAY
WITH TWIZZLERS,
THE TWIST YOU CAN'T RESIST.
SAM: EIGHT MONTHS AFTER
BEING ATTACKED BY
MULTIPLE SHARKS, OUR
BOTTLENOSE DOLPHIN IS
HEALED AND READY TO
RETURN TO THE SEA.
STEVE: WE HAD SEVERAL
CONCERNS WITH RELEASING
C6 TO THE WILD: THE FACT
THAT HE WAS AN OLDER
DOLPHIN, THE FACT THAT
HE HAD SOME MILD MEDICAL
CONDITIONS, LIKE THE
CATARACT TO HIS LEFT
EYE.
MAN: COME ON, LAZY BOY.
SAM: THE TEAM IS
CONFIDENT HE'S STRONG
ENOUGH TO MAKE IT.
IT'S A BITTERSWEET
MOMENT, BUT ONE
EVERYONE'S BEEN WORKING
TOWARD.
MAN: HE'S BREATHING'S
GOOD.
HE'S GOT DIMPLES.
HE DIDN'T HAVE THOSE
WHEN HE CAME.
SAM: AFTER A FINAL CHECK
OF HIS VITALS, C6 IS
TAKEN THE SHORT DISTANCEOM O
FROM HARBOR BRANCH TO
THE EDGE OF THE INDIAN
RIVER.
IT'S BEEN EIGHT MONTHS
SINCE THE NEAR FATAL
SHARK ATTACK.
MAN: GOOD JOB.
SAM: AND EVERYONE'S
EXCITED ABOUT HIS
RETURN.
DR. DOLD: THIS HAS BEEN
A LONG EFFORT TO
REHABILITATE HIM; BUT
THE FACT THAT HE IS NOW
READY FOR RETURN, IT
REALLY MAKES THE WORK
THAT EVERYONE HAS
DEDICATED TO THIS ANIMAL
THAT MUCH MORE
SUBSTANTIAL.
SAM: THE TEAM BRINGS C6
OUT OF THE WATER, AS A
CROWD GATHERS ON SHORE.
[CHEERING/APPLAUSE]
SAM: OUR DOLPHIN TAKES
ONE LOOK AT THE OPEN
WATER, AND WITH A KICK
OF HIS POWERFUL FLUKE,
HE HEADS TOWARD HOME.
MAN: GO, BUDDY!
[CHEERING/APPLAUSE]
MAN: SO FAR, SO GOOD,
HUH?
SAM: IT'S BEEN EIGHT
LONG MONTHS, AND C6'S
REMARKABLE JOURNEY HOME
IS THE REWARDING SIGHT
EVERY RESCUER HOPES FOR.JOND
JON: SPENDING YOUR WHOLE
EVENING TRYING TO CATCH
A DOLPHIN IS A REALLY
COOL JOB, BUT THE BEST
PART OF THE JOB IS
HEARING THAT THAT
DOLPHIN HAS RECUPERATED
AND HAS BEEN RELEASED
BACK TO THE WILD.
THAT IS THE BEST PART OF
THIS JOB.
MAN: AND NOW IT'S OUR
JOB AND RESPONSIBILITY
TO FOLLOW HIM UP TO MAKE
SURE THAT HE THRIVES AND
DOES WELL.
SAM: EVEN THOUGH C6 IS
HEALTHY, THE TEAM IS
WORRIED.
HE IS 26 YEARS OLD, AND
THAT'S OLD FOR A DOLPHIN
IN THE WILD, SO RESCUERS
DECIDE TO MONITOR HIS
PROGRESS.
STEVE: WE PLACED A SMALL
RADIO TAG ON C6'S DORSAL
FIN.
THE VHF TAG ALLOWS
RESEARCHERS WITH
RECEIVERS TO TRACK THE
DOLPHIN, SO THAT WE CAN
DOCUMENT HIS BEHAVIOR.
SAM: A MONTH LATER,
STEVE TRACKS C6'S SIGNAL
TO CHECK UP ON OUR
DOLPHIN.
STEVE: DURING OUR
THREE-DAY POST RELEASE
MONITORING EFFORT, WE
WERE ABLE TO TRACK C6,
HIS CONSISTENT DIRECTION
NORTH, AND HE SEEMED TO
KNOW WHERE HE WAS GOING.
SAM: THE CREW FOLLOWS
THE SIGNAL TO THE EXACT
SPOT WHERE C6 SHOULD BE,
BUT HE'S NOWHERE TO BE
FOUND.
MAN: NOTHING HERE.
SAM: THEY FINALLY SPOT
THAT FAMILIAR NOTCHED
FIN.
MAN: THAT'S HIM!
I GOT HIM!
SAM: AND ARE THRILLED TO
FIND THAT C6 IS NOT ONLY
ALIVE, BUT THRIVING.
MAN: WOO, HA, HA!
I LOVE IT!
MAN, THIS IS GREAT.
SAM: AND MORE GOOD NEWS.
RESCUERS SPOT ANOTHER
RECOGNIZABLE DORSAL FIN
NEARBY.
MAN: HE'S WITH 7!
SAM: C6'S FAITHFUL
COMPANION FOR THE PAST
20 YEARS, C7, SWIMS
RIGH
RIGHT UP BESIDE HIM.
MAN: OH, MY GOODNESS!
LOOK AT THAT!
STEVE: WE WERE STUNNED
TO SEE HIM IN THE
COMPANY OF THREE FEMALE
DOLPHINS AND HIS PARTNER
OF ALMOST 20 YEARS, C7.
AND FOR US, THAT WAS A
STUNNING ACHIEVEMENT AND
A TRUE TESTIMONY OF THE
DOLPHIN'S INSTINCT AND
SKILLS IN THE WILD.
DR. DOLD: FOR THEM TO
REUNITE, RE-ESTABLISH
THAT BOND, AND GO ABOUT
THEIR LIVES AFTER THIS
SUBSTANTIAL
REHABILITATION EFFORT,
IT'S NOT JUST REWARDING.
IT'S ALSO FASCINATING
AND A REALLY GREAT
REMINDER OF WHY WE ARE
SO INTERESTED IN THESE
ANIMALS.
SAM: THESE MOMENTS ARE
THE PAYOFF FOR THE
PASSION AND COMMITMENT
OF ALL THE INDIVIDUALS
WHO TOOK PART IN THIS
RESCUE.
STEVE: BEING ABLE TO
RETURN HIM TO HIS
LIFETIME PARTNER, C7, IS
BEYOND REWARDING.
IT'S ENRICHING.
FOR A RESEARCHER AND
REHABILITATION
SPECIALIST, THIS IS THE
PINNACLE OF YOUR WORK.
SAM: THE STORY OF C6 AND
C7 IS NOT ONLY ONE OF
SURVIVAL.
IT'S ALSO A STUDY IN
BROTHERLY LOVE.
IT TEACHES US THAT WE
HAVE A LOT TO LEARN
ABOUT THE COMPLEX DRAMAS
PLAYING OUT EVERY DAY
BENEATH THE OCEAN'S
WAVES.
I'M SAM CHAMPION, AND
WE'LL SEE YOU NEXT WEEK
WHEN WE GO ON ANOTHER
SEA RESCUE.
CLOSED CAPTIONING AND
OTHER PROMOTIONAL
CONSIDERATION PROVIDED
[ Female Announcer ]
What would you call
an ordinary breakfast pastry
that's been wrapped
in a flaky crust
stuffed with a gooey center
toasted up all golden brown
A toaster strudel.
Pillsbury Toaster Strudel.
So Delicious...So Fun.
And when I get a cold I take
Coricidin HBP.
The number one pharmacist
recommended cold brand
designed for people with high
blood pressure.
Coricidin HBP.
♪ MUSIC
DANNY: HELLO, I'M DANNY
BOOME, AND WELCOME TO
RECIPE REHAB, SPONSORED
BY EVERYDAY HEALTH.
ON THIS WEEK'S EPISODE,
THE MAJORS LOVE THEIR
FRIED CHICKEN RECIPE.
DEVIN: ALL RIGHT, WHO'S
READY FOR SOME CHICKEN?
VICTORIA: I LOVE FRIED
CHICKEN.
DEVIN: TO THE FRIED
GOODNESS.
VICTORIA: MY DAD PUTS,
LIKE, A LOT OF OIL IN
HIS CHICKEN.
DANNY: BUT WITH MORE