WHO LOST HER SMALL CHILDREN IN A
BATHROOM AND PROMISED THEY WOULD
LIVE TO SEE CHRISTMAS.
>> TELLING THEM IT'S GOING TO BE
OKAY, YOU'RE GOING TO BE ALL
RIGHT.
>> AT THE WHITE HOUSE, TODAY THE
PRESIDENT, WEEPING.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
>> OUR ABC NEWS TEAM HERE TO
BRING YOU THE LATEST ON THE
WORST SHOOTING AT AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN AMERICAN HISTORY AS
"WORLD NEWS" BEGINS TONIGHT.
>> FROM ABC NEWS, THIS IS A
SPECIAL EDITION OF "WORLD NEWS"
WITH DIANE SAWYER, TRAGEDY AT
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
REPORTING FROM CONNECTICUT,
DIANE SAWYER.
>> GOOD EVENING, WELCOME TO A
SPECIAL EDITION OF "WORLD NEWS"
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, THE
SITE OF A MASS SHOOTING AND
GUNFIRE AIMED AT ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL CHILDREN.
WE'RE IN FRONT OF THE UNITED
METHODIST CHURCH WHERE PEOPLE
ARE GATHERING ALL EVEN LONG AS
DETAILS ARE STILL POURING IN.
27 VICTIMS, 20 CHILDREN, SEVEN
ADULTS AND WE HEARD ALL DAY
ABOUT THE INCREDIBLE RESPONSE BY
TEACHERS INSIDE THE SCHOOL WHICH
IS CONSIDERED ONE OF THE LEADING
SCHOOLS IN THE NATION.
AND ALSO TONIGHT, WE HAVE A NEW
IMAGE OF THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER,
AS WE TELL YOU EVERYTHING WE
KNOW ABOUT WHO DID IT, WHAT KIND
OF WEAPONS AND WHY.
AND WE BEGIN ALL OF THIS WITH
BETWEEN BETWEEN ANCHOR CHRIS
CUOMO AND HE'S HERE WITH ME.
>> ALMOST UNIMAGINABLE SCENE.
WHAT WE KNOW SO FAR IS INSIDE
THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, YOUNG
KID PROCESS TEKTD BY THEIR
TEACHERS AND THERE WAS ONE
DERANGED MAN WHO DECIDED TO TAKE
IT ALL AWAY.
>> THIS MORNING, THE SCHOOL WAS
FILLED WITH KIDS CONCERNED ABOUT
CHRISTMAS.
THEN SHOTS RANG OUT.
>> THE INDIVIDUAL I HAVE ON THE
PHONE IS CONTINUING TO HEAR WHAT
WHAT HE BELIEVES IS GUN FIRE.
>> Reporter: INSIDE, LITTLE KIDS
ARE UNER ATTACK.
>> WE HEARD ALL THIS RACKET.
>> HORRIBLE THINGS ARE
HAPPENING.
TEACHERS MAKE SURE THEY'RE SAFE
AND DO THE UNIMAGINABLE.
>> Reporter: WHAT THE TEACHER DO
THEN?
>> SHE READ US SOME BOOKS AND WE
TALKED ABOUT THINGS AND PLAYED
LITTLE GAMES IN THERE.
>> Reporter: DID YOU HEAR ANY
MORE BAD NOISES?
>> YES.
>> Reporter: THE TEACHERS' CALM
IS MATCHED BY A POLICE OF STORM
ACTIVITY, WORD OF POSSIBLY TWO
SHOOTERS SPARKS SEARCHES OF THE
SURROUNDING AREA.
CHILDREN RUSHED OUT OF THE
SCHOOL, SINGLE-FILE HANDS ON
SHOULDER, EYES SQUEEZED SHUT.
>> WE GOT IN LINE AND WE HAD TO
CLOSE OUR EYES.
>> Reporter: HOW DID YOU FIND
YOUR WAY OUT WITH YOUR EYES
CLOSED?
>> WE ALL PUT OUR HANDS ON OTHER
PEOPLE'S SHOULDERS AND THEN OUR
TEACHER HOLD THE FIRST PERSON'S
HAND AND SHE LED US OUT.
>> CHAOS.
COMPLETE CHAOS.
NOBODY KNEW WHERE ANYONE WAS,
MOB SCENE OF CHILDREN AND POLICE
AND ADULTS.
>> Reporter: ELLA'S MOM AND
DOZENS OF OTHER FAMILIES SEARCH
FOR THEIR KIDS AS INFORMATION
STARKS TO TRICKLE IN.
>> I HEARD THAT CHILDREN WERE
TAKEN OUT BLOODY.
>> VERY SCARED, WORRIED ABOUT MY
SON, WORRIED ABOUT THE OTHER
KIDS I KNOW HERE.
>> IT WAS TERRIFYING, I'M STILL
TERRIFIED.
I'M STILL IN SHOCK ABOUT IT ALL.
I STILL DON'T KNOW EVERYTHING
THAT HAPPENED.
>> Reporter: A SITUATION THAT
COULDN'T BE ANY MORE TERRIFYING.
KIDS AT THE MERCY OF A DERANGED
GUNMAN.
AND YET, IT KEEPS GETTING WORSE.
>> I NEED UNITS IN THE SCHOOL.
I GOT BODIES HERE.
>> Reporter: AMONG THE DEAD
20SHGS-YEAR-OLD GUNMAN ADAM
LANZA, HIS MOTHER A TEACHERS AN
AIDE AT THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
HE CAME WITH A BULLETPROOF VEST
AND TWO SEMI AUTOMATIC GUNS
POSSIBLY AN ASSAULT RIFLE.
HE KILLED SO MANY OF THE KIDS
SHE LOVED.
>> VERY DIFFICULT SCENE FOR THE
FAMILY MEMBERS, RESPONDING FIRST
RESPONDERS, A TRAGEDY.
A TRAGIC SCENE.
>> Reporter: AND YET, MANY MORE
SURVIVE, LIKE LITTLE ELLA WHO
WILL STILL HAVE A CHANCE AT A
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
>> IT'S OVER.
OKAY?
YOU KNOW THAT NOW?
>> YES.
>> Reporter: ALL OF THE
SURVIVORS, THEY ARE SO YOUNG AND
THAT MAKES IT SO TRAGIC AND AT
THE SAME TIME FAMILIES HOPING
THEY'RE YOUNG ENOUGH TO FORGET
AND MOVE ON WITH THEIR LIVES.
>> TELL US THE LATEST DETAILS
WHAT WE LEARNED ABOUT WHY AND
MOTIVE OF THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER.
>> Reporter: ALWAYS SO IMPORTANT
US TO, ONE THING WE CAN LEARN IN
THE SITUATION, WHAT DROVE THIS
PERSON TO THIS HORRIBLE THING
AND YET NOW IT'S GETTING MORE
CONFUSING.
AUTHORITIES NOW BELIEVE THAT THE
GUNMAN'S MOTHER WAS FOUND KILLED
IN HER HOME.
NOT AT THE SCHOOL.
SO, THE QUESTION REMAINS LARGER
THAN EVER Y DID THIS MAN GO TO
THE SCHOOL?
WHY DID HE ATTACK THE KIDS WITH
SUCH INTENSITY?
>> SO MANY YOUNG KIDS.
WE KNOW DETAILS ARE STILL COMING
IN, AS WE'VE BEEN SAYING AND
WE'LL BRING YOU UP TO DATE
THROUGH THIS HOUR IN THIS
SPECIAL BROADCAST.
>>> AS WE DROVE IN TO TOWN YOU
SAW THE BEAUTIFUL HILLS COMING
INTO THIS INCREDIBLY WONDERFUL
TOWN AND TONIGHT, WE SEE THE
FLAGS AT HALF STAFF RIGHT HERE
IN NEWTOWN AND ACROSS THE
COUNTRY THE FLAGS ARE ALSO AT
HALF-STAFF AS TODAY PRESIDENT
OBAMA ADDRESSED THE NATION.
TEARING UP AS HE TALKED ABOUT
THE GRIEVING PARENTS AND THEIR
SMALL CHILDREN.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN,
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM -- BIRTHDAYS,
GRADUATIONS, WEDDINGS, KIDS OF
THEIR OWN.
>> AS WE HAVE SAID ALL DAY, WE
HAVE MET PEOPLE THAT REMIND US
WHAT TEACHERS DO, HOW MUCH THEY
CARE EVEN IN THE FACE OF TERROR
AND I SAT DOWN WITH A FIRST
GRADE TEACHER AT THAT SCHOOL,
KAITLIN ROIG, SHE HEARD GUN
FIRE, LARGE WINDOWS EXPOSED HER
CLA
CLASSROOM SO SHE MANAGED TO RUSH
15 SMALL CHILDREN INTO A TINY
BATHROOM TO TRY TO SAVE THEIR
LIVES.
>> I PUT ONE OF MY STUDENTS ON
TOP, I KNEW WE HAD TO GET IN
THERE, I TOLD THEM IT'S GOING TO
BE OKAY.
YOU'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
I PULLED A BOOK SHELF IN FRONT
OF IT SO WE WERE COMPLETELY
BARRICADED IN.
I TURNED THE LIGHTS OFF.
>> Reporter: DID YOU TELL THEM
TO BE QUIET?
DID YOU WORRY --
>> I TOLD THEM TO BE QUIET,
ABSOLUTELY QUIET.
BECAUSE I WAS JUST SO AFRAID IF
HE CAME IN AND HEAR US AND START
SHOOTING THE DOOR.
I SAID WE HAVE TO BE ABSOLUTELY
QUIET AND WE HAVE -- I SAID
THERE ARE BAD GUYS OUT THERE AND
WE NEED TO WAIT FOR THE GOOD
GUYS.
I WANTED US TO BE OKAY.
AND I WAS SO SADDENED THERE WERE
PEOPLE WHO IN THIS SITUATION ARE
NOT OKAY.
AND MY HEART GOES OUT TO ANYONE
WHO KNEW THEM AND WAS PART OF
THEIR LIVES.
I CAN'T IMAGINE.
>> Reporter: DID THEY CRY?
>> IF THEY STARTED CRYING I
WOULD TAKE THEIR FACE AND SAY
IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY, SHOW ME
YOUR SMILE.
I REALLY TRIED -- ONE OF MY
STUDENTS WOULD SAY LIKE I KNOW
CAKARAT
KARATE, I'LL LEAD THE WAY OUT.
>> Reporter: THEY REALLY SAID TO
YOU, WE WANT TO GO HOME FOR
CHRISTMAS?
>> OH, YEAH.
I JUST WANT TO HUG MY MOM,
THINGS LIKE THAT, THAT WERE
JUST, IT'S HEARTBREAKING.
BECAUSE YOU'RE HEARING -- I'VE
NEVER BEEN PART OF SOMETHING
ANYWHERE NEAR THIS TRAUMATIC AND
SO I'M HEARING THE GUNFIRE IN
THE HALLWAY, I'M IN THE FIRST
CLASSROOM.
WHY ISN'T HE COMING?
I'M THINKING WE'RE NEXT.
IN MY MIND I'M THINKING, AS A
6-YEAR-OLD, 7-YEAR-OLD, WHAT ARE
YOUR THOUGHTS?
AND THINKING THAT I HAVE TO
ALMOST BE THEIR PARENT, I HAVE
TO TELL THEM -- I SAID I NEED
YOU TO KNOW THAT I WILL LOVE YOU
ALL VERY MUCH AND THAT IT'S
GOING TO BE OKAY.
I NOW THE THAT WAS THE LAST
THING THEY WERE EVER GOING TO
HEAR.
I THOUGHT WE WERE ALL GOING TO
DIE.
I DON'T KNOW IF THAT'S OKAY,
TEACHERS, I WANTED THEM TO KNOW
SOMEONE LOVED THEM AND I WANTED
THAT TO BE ONE OF THE LAST
THINGS THEY HEARD, NOT THE G
GUNFIRE IN THE HALLWAY.
SO HORRIBLE.
HORRIBLE.
HORRIBLE, HORRIBLE.
>> Reporter: HOW DID YOU KNOW
YOU WERE GOING TO BE OKAY?
>> I DIDN'T.
WHAT FINALLY HAPPENED, GUNTIRE
STOPPED, IT WASN'T THAT LONG,
THAT STOPPED BUT I SAID WE'RE
NOT GOING ANYWHERE, WE'RE
STAYING HERE UNTIL SOMEONE GOOD
GETS US OUT.
SO, EVEVENEVENTUALLY THE POLICE
AND STARTED KNOCKING AND I WAS
COMPLETELY BESIDE MYSELF, I SAID
I DON'T BELIEVE YOU.
PUT YOUR BADGES UNDER THE DOOR.
THEY PUT THEIR BADGES UNDER THE
DOOR.
I SAID IF YOU'RE REALLY A POLICE
OFFICER YOU WOULD HAVE A WAY TO
GET N A KEY OR GOTTEN IT, IF
EVERYTHING IS OKAY YOU WOULD
HAVE FOUND THE KEYS.
HE FOUND THE RIGHT ONE AND
UNLOCKED THE DOOR AND THEY
BROUGHT US OUT TO THE FIREHOUSE
WITH THE REST OF THE TEACHERS
AND STUDENTS WAITING FOR PARENTS
TO COME AND PICK THEM UP.
>> Reporter: I THINK A LOT OF
PEOPLE WHO WISH, WANT ALL OF THE
TEACHERS TO KNOW HOW MUCH IT
MEANS TO THEM HOW MUCH MUCH THEY
CARE ABOUT THEIR CHILDREN.
>> HOW COULD YOU NOT?
>> Reporter: THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> AND SHE ONLY SPOKE, SHE
SAID, BECAUSE SHE WANTS US TO
KNOW THIS IS A SCHOOL OF
TEACHERS WHO CARE SO MUCH ABOUT
EACH OTHER AND THEIR STUDENTS.
SHE WAITED TO PAY TRIBUTE TO ALL
OF THEM TONIGHT AND SHE IS
PRAYING FOR ALL OF THOSE WHO ARE
GRIEVING.
>>> AND AS CHRIS SAID EARLIER
WE'RE STILL GETTING NEW DETAILS
ABOUT THE SUSPECTED SHOOTER,
ADAM LANZA, SO MANY QUESTIONS
ABOUT WHO HE IS, WHAT MAY HAVE
DRIVEN HIM DO THIS, ABC'S CHIEF
INVESTIGATIVE REPORTER BRIAN
ROSS TRACKING REPORTS AS THEY
COME IN.
HE HAS THE LATEST.
>> Reporter: TONIGHT POLICE
IDENTIFIED THE SHOOTER AS
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA IN A
PICTURE HERE TAKEN 7 YEARS AGO
AND PROVIDED TO ABC NEWS BY A
FAMILY FRIEND.
A RELATIVE TOLD ABC NEWS THAT
DAM WAS OBVIOUSLY NOT WELL.
SOMETHING WE ALSO HEARD FROM
FAMILY FRIENDS IN NEWTOWN WHO
DESCRIBED THE YOUNG MAN AS
TROUBLED, DESCRIBED HIS MOTHER
NANCY AS VERY RIGID.
THIS ALL TOOK PLACE IN THIS TINY
CONNECTICUT TOWN, A SHOOTING
SPREE THAT ENDED AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL BUT FIRST
BEGAN AT THE LANZA FAMILY HOME,
WHICH WAS NEARBY.
POLICE LATE TODAY SAID HIS
MOTHER'S BODY WAS FOUND IN THE
FAMILY HOME.
STATE AND FEDERAL AUTHORITIES
BELIEVE HIS MOTHER MAY HAVE ONCE
WORKED AT THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
WHERE ADAM WENT ON HIS DEADLY
RAMPAGE, ALTHOUGH HE WAS NOT A
TEACHER, PERHAPS A VOLUNTEER.
AUTHORITIES ALSO SEARCHED THE
NEW JERSEY APARTMENT OF ADAM'S
OLDER BROTHER RYAN IN HOBOKEN.
POLICE INITIALLY IDENTIFIED RYAN
AS THE KILLER UNLESS NL SHE SENT
OUT TWEETS SAYING IT WASN'T ME,
I WAS AT WORK ALL DAY.
POLICE ARE QUESTIONING WRY RYIAN
AND HIS FATHER AT A NEW JERSEY
POLICE STATION AND FEDERAL ALTHS
AND STATE PLUS WANT TO KNOW WHY
THAT YOUNG MEN WAS SET OFF, WHAT
CAUSED THAT AND HOW AND WEN WHE
HE ACCUMULATED SUCH AN ARAVE
WEAPONS AND AMMUNITION.
>> INVESTIGATING THE STORY,
BRIAN ROSS TONIGHT.
AND OF COURSE, IT IS AN
INCREDIBLY SOMBER TASK TO TALK
TO THE FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS
AND ONE MONSIGNOR TALKED ABOUT
HOW DIFFICULT IT CAN BE.
>> THE REALITY HAS SET IN THAT
THESE 20 CHILDREN ARE WITH THE
LORD AND TAKEN TOO YOUNG AND TOO
INNOCENT AND WE JUST TOLD A
LITTLE BOY ABOUT HIS SISTER NOW,
A
AND -- SO SORRY.
A LOT OF THESE PEOPLE ARE FROM
OUR PARISH, WHICH MAKES IT
PRETTY HEAVY FOR ME, TOO, I
BAPTIZED SOME OF THESE CHILDREN
AND THEY WERE GETTING READY FOR
MIRS COMMUNION.
>> AN ENTIRE COMMUNITY DOING
WHAT IT CAN TONIGHT.
>>> STILL AHEAD ON "WORLD NEWS,"
A QUESTION AMERICAN FAMILIES
GRAPPLING WITH, HOW TO TALK TO
CHILDREN ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED.
DR. RICHARD BESSER TO WEIGH IN
WITH THE ONE THING THAT MIGHT
HELP HEAL THEM, TONIGHT.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS SHELDON, WHOSE LONG DY
SETTING UP THE NEWS
STARTS WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND A CHOICE.
TAKE TYLENOL OR TAKE ALEVE,
THE #1 RECOMMENDED PAIN
RELIEVER BY ORTHOPEDIC DOCTORS.
JUST TWO ALEVE
CAN KEEP PAIN AWAY ALL DAY.
BACK TO THE NEWS.
But when I was in an accident...
CAN KEEP PAIN AWAY ALL DAY.
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
So I never missed a beat.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
♪
>>> AND TONIGHT ALL ACROSS THE
COUNTRY AMERICAN FAMILIES ARE
SEEING THOSE IMAGES OF TRAGEDY.
SMALL CHILDREN HEARING WHAT
HAPPENED AT AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
SO WE ASKED ABC'S CHIEF MEDICAL
EDITOR, DR. RICHARD BESSER, FOR
A GUIDE ON WHAT YOU SAY TO YOUR
CHILDREN.
>> JUST AS ADULTS SCRAMBLED
TODAY TO PROTECT CHILDREN, THERE
ARE THINGS YOU CAN DO TONIGHT TO
PROTECT CHILDREN FROM THE
VULNERABLE EMOTIONS FROM THE
TRAGEDY AFFECTING US ALL.
HOW YOU DO THAT WILL DEPEND ON
THEIR AGE.
IF YOUR CHILD IS 7 OR UNDER AND
IS SITTING WITH YOU RIGHT NOW,
MY ADVICE, LET THEM GO INTO
ANOTHER ROOM.
IF THEY HAVEN'T HEARD ABOUT THE
SHOOTING, THEY DON'T NEED TO
KNOW ABOUT IT.
YOU KNOW YOUR CHILD BEST.
IF THEY'RE BETWEEN 7 AND 12,
TALK TO THEM ABOUT IT.
DON'T LIE, DON'T EVADE, BUT TELL
THEM THEY'RE SAFE.
SOMETHING LIKE THIS, WHERE
SOMEONE HURTS A CHILD IN SCHOOL,
IS SO INCREDIBLY RARE.
IT NEVER HAPPENED TO MOM OR DAD
OR ANYONE WE KNOW.
AND THE MAN WHO DID IT IS GONE
NOW.
IT'S OVER.
ASK HOW THEY FEEL ABOUT IT.
TELL THEM IT'S OKAY TO BE SAD,
THAT YOU'RE SAD.
SUPPORT WHATEVER THEY FEEL AND
TELL THEM THAT YOU'LL KEEP THEM
SAFE.
BUT SHARING EXTRA HUGS WILL HAVE
MORE EFFECT ON THEIR BODY
CHEMISTRY THAN ASKING OVER AND
OVER IF THEY'RE ALL RIGHT.
FOR TEENS, WATCH TO SEE HOW THEY
REACT.
ASK THEM TO TALK ABOUT IT.
YOU CAN USE THIS TO HAVE A REAL
CONVERSATION.
WHY DO THEY THINK IT HAPPENED?
YOU MIGHT WANT TO DIRECT THEM TO
SOME VOLUNTEER WORK, SO THEY
FEEL THEY CAN BE WORKING TO
IMPROVE THINGS.
FOR ALL KIDS, KEEP YOUR ROUTINE.
CHILDREN ARE REASSURED IF THEIR
WORLD CONTINUES IN A NORMAL WAY.
BEDTIME IS BEDTIME TONIGHT,
BASKETBALL PRACTICE, IT HAPPENS
TOMORROW.
IT SHOWS THEM THE WORLD IS STILL
NORMAL.
IF THEY WANT YOU TO TAKE THEM TO
SCHOOL ON MONDAY, THAT'S FINE.
BUT GOING BACK TO SCHOOL ON
MONDAY PROVES TO THEM THAT
YOU'RE NOT WORRIED, SO THEY
WON'T BE.
IF YOU'RE A PARENT, THIS CAN BE
TRAUMATIC FOR YOU AS WELL.
REACH OUT AND ASK FOR EXTRA
HUGS, TALK WITH YOUR FRIENDS.
YOU HAVE TO TAKE CARE OF
YOURSELF TO BE THERE FOR YOUR
CHILDREN.
>> TELL US ABOUT THE SIGNS OF
SOMETHING WRONG, EVEN IF YOUR
CHILD DOESN'T TELL YOU.
>> IT'S NORMAL TO HAVE A STRESS
REACTION, A CHILD WHO IS NOT
SLEEPING, NOT EATING, WHO CAN'T
FOCUS.
A CHILD WHO IS HYPERWORRIED,
THEY CAN'T THINK ABOUT ANYTHING
ELSE, WHO'S NOT ABLE TO RETURN
TO NORMAL ACTIVITIES AFTER A
WEEK OR TWO, THEY NEED TO GET
SPECIAL HELP.
>> AND DON'T ASSUME BECAUSE THEY
SAY NOTHING THEY'RE NOT FEELING
SOMETHING.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> THANK YOU, RICH.
>>> COMING UP, WE KEPT HEARING
ABOUT THE TRAINING THE TEACHERS
RECEIVED INSIDE THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL THEY NEVER
DREAMED THEY WOULD HAVE TO USE
IT, BUT YOU'RE GOING TO HEAR HOW
THEY WERE TRAINED AND WHAT THEY
DID TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS BOB,
A REGULAR GUY
WITH AN IRREGULAR HEARTBEAT.
THE USUAL, BOB?
NOT TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
BOB HAS AFIB:
ATRIAL FIBRILLATION NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
A CONDITION THAT PUTS HIM
AT GREATER RISK FOR A STROKE.
[ GPS ] TURN LEFT.
I DON'T THINK SO.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR YEARS, BOB TOOK WARFARIN,
AND MADE A MONTHLY TRIP TO THE
CLINIC TO GET HIS BLOOD TESTED.
BUT NOT ANYMORE.
BOB'S DOCTOR RECOMMENDED
A DIFFERENT OPTION:
ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
XARELTO® IS THE FIRST AND ONLY
ONCE-A-DAY PRESCRIPTION
BLOOD THINNER
FOR PATIENTS WITH AFIB
NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
THAT DOESN'T REQUIRE
ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING.
LIKE WARFARIN,
XARELTO® IS PROVEN EFFECTIVE
TO REDUCE THE RISK
OF AN AFIB-RELATED STROKE.
THERE IS LIMITED DATA
ON HOW THESE DRUGS COMPARE
WHEN WARFARIN IS WELL MANAGED.
NO ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING
MEANS BOB CAN SPEND HIS
EXTRA TIME HOWEVER HE LIKES.
NEW ZEALAND!
XARELTO®
IS JUST ONE PILL A DAY,
TAKEN WITH THE EVENING MEAL.
AND WITH
NO DIETARY RESTRICTIONS,
BOB CAN EAT THE HEALTHY FOODS
HE LIKES.
DO NOT STOP TAKING
XARELTO® RIVAROXABAN
WITHOUT TALKING TO THE DOCTOR
WHO PRESCRIBES IT FOR YOU.
STOPPING MAY INCREASE YOUR RISK
OF HAVING A STROKE.
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU DEVELOP ANY SIGNS
OR SYMPTOMS OF BLEEDING,
LIKE UNUSUAL BRUISING
OR TINGLING.
YOU MAY HAVE A HIGHER RISK
OF BLEEDING
IF YOU TAKE XARELTO®
WITH ASPIRIN PRODUCTS,
NSAIDS OR BLOOD THINNERS.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE TAKING XARELTO®
IF YOU CURRENTLY HAVE
ABNORMAL BLEEDING.
XARELTO® CAN CAUSE BLEEDING,
WHICH CAN BE SERIOUS,
AND RARELY MAY LEAD TO DEATH.
YOU ARE LIKELY TO BRUISE
MORE EASILY ON XARELTO®,
AND IT MAY TAKE LONGER
FOR BLEEDING TO STOP.
TELL YOUR DOCTORS
YOU ARE TAKING XARELTO®
BEFORE ANY PLANNED MEDICAL
OR DENTAL PROCEDURES.
BEFORE STARTING XARELTO®,
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ANY CONDITIONS,
SUCH AS KIDNEY, LIVER
OR BLEEDING PROBLEMS.
READY TO CHANGE YOUR ROUTINE?
ASK YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
FOR MORE INFORMATION
INCLUDING COST SUPPORT OPTIONS,
CALL 1-888-XARELTO
OR VISIT GOXARELTO.COM.
>>> AS WE SAID, THE TEACHERS AT
THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
HAD BEEN TRAINED TO REACT TO A
THREAT, NEVER EXPECTING TO USE
THAT TRAINING.
ABC'S AMY ROBACH IS WITH US NOW
AND SHE TELLS US WHAT THE
TRAINING WAS AND EXACTLY WHAT
THEY DID.
AMY?
>> THAT'S RIGHT, WE'RE HERE AT
DANBURY HOSPITAL WHERE THE
MEDICAL STAFF TOLD US THEY
THOUGHT IT MUST HAVE BEEN A LOT
LIKE 9/11 BECAUSE THEY HAD THEIR
ENTIRE STAFF WAITING HERE TO
RECEIVE THE INJURED.
ONLY THREE ARRIVED.
THE DEATH COUNT UNIMAGINABLE,
BUT AS YOU MENTIONED, SO MANY
PEOPLE ARE ATTRIBUTING THAT
NUMBER TO THE HEROIC ACTS OF
TEACHERS.
IF IT WEREN'T FOR THEIR BRAVERY,
MANY IN THE COMMUNITY BELIEVE
THAT NUMBER WOULD HAVE BEEN EVEN
HIGHER.
>> Reporter: FOR THE NEARLY 700
STUDENTS WHO ATTEND SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, IT IS THE
TEACHERS' WORDS THEY FOLLOW DAY
IN AND DAY OUT.
TODAY, THOSE WORDS MIGHT HAVE
JUST SAVED THEIR LIFE.
>> HIS TEACHER WENT AND CHECKED,
LOCKED AND CLOSED THE DOOR.
THEY WENT INTO A CORNER UNTIL
THEY WERE RECOVERED BY POLICE.
>> THE TEACHER PUT THEM IN THE
CORNER AND THEY WEREN'T ALLOWED
TO MOVE UNTIL THE POLICE CAME.
>> THIS RAUNT RESTAURANT HAS
BEEN SERVING PIZZA TO SANDY HOOK
PARENTS AND TEACHERS FOR MORE
THAN 30 YEARS.
>> THEY'RE ALL HEROES.
>> IT DOES SOUND THAT THE
TEACHERS DID EVERYTHING HUMANLY
POSSIBLE, DOWN TO RISKING THEIR
OWN LIVES TO PROTECT THE
CHILDREN IN THIS CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL.
ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY HAVE BEEN PREPARING FOR
LOCKDOWN DRILLS, EVACUATIONS,
AND OTHER SECURITY MEASURES
SINCE COLUMBINE.
>> Reporter: JUST THIS YEAR,
SANDY HOOK PUT INTO PLACE A
SECURITY PLAN, MAKING IT
MANDATORY FOR VISITORS TO RING A
DO
DOORBELL AND ONLY ALOUD IN IF
STAFF RECOGNIZED THE VISITOR.
AND IF STAFF DIDN'T RECOGNIZE
THE VISITOR, HE OR SHE NEEDED TO
PRESENT PICTURE I.D., SIGN IN
AND ONLY THEN WOULD BE LET INTO
THE SCHOOL.
>> EVERY TIME WE WENT TO THE
SCHOOL, YOU HAD TO PRESS THE
BUTTON, THEY'D ASK WHO YOU ARE
TO COME IN.
I DON'T KNOW HOW ANYBODY COULD
JUST WALK IN.
>> THIS TWEET FROM SOMEONE WHO
KNEW TEACHERS INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
>> HANNAH GREEN, MY COUSIN IS
THE ASSISTANT PRINCIPAL AND WAS
SHOT TWICE, NOW IN SURGERY.
>> THIS FACE TELLING IT ALL,
THIS WOMAN'S SISTER, ONE OF
THOSE TEACHERS INSIDE THE
SCHOOL, HER WHEREABOUTS UNKNOWN.
>> THERE'S NO WORDS THAT I COULD
COME UP.
YOU DON'T KNOW THE DETAILS OF
THE VIOLENCE AND YOU CAN'T DO
ANYTHING TO IMMEDIATELY HELP
THEM OR PROTECT THEM.
THAT IS A POWERLESS AND
TERRIFYING EXPERIENCE.
>> Reporter: SPEAKING OF
POWERLESS, I JUST SPOKE TO ONE
OF THE DOCTORS HERE WHO WAS AT
DANBURY HOSPITAL WHEN THEY
RECEIVED THE INITIAL CALL OF
MULTIPLE SHOTS FIRED AT
THE SCHOOL.
HE AMASSED 80 DOCTORS AND NURSES
WAITING TO RECEIVE ANY POTENTIAL
VICTIMS AND INJURED.
WITHIN THE FIRST TEN MINUTES,
THEY GOT THOSE INITIAL THREE
INJURED AND THEY WERE WAITING
FOR MORE.
THEY WERE TOLD AS MANY AS TWO
DOZEN THEY WOULD RECEIVE.
WITHIN 30 MINUTES WHEN THEY
DIDN'T SHOW UP, THAT'S WHEN THEY
FELT THE GRAVITY OF THE
SITUATION BECAUSE THEY KNEW THEY
WEREN'T COMING, THEY WERE AT THE
SCHOOL AND WOULD STAY THERE
FOREVER.
IT WAS A VERY DISTURBING MOMENT
FOR ALL OF THEM.
THEY SAID THEY'RE STILL GOING TO
BE DEALING WITH THIS OBVIOUSLY
FOR MONTHS AND YEARS TO COME.
THIS COMMUNITY IS FOREVER
CHANGED.
NO ONE HERE HASN'T BEEN TOUCHED
BY THIS HORRIFIC TRAGEDY.
>> AND NO ONE IN THE COUNTRY,
AMY.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR REPORTING
TONIGHT.
>>> WHEN WE COME BACK, WE HAVE
BEEN RECEIVING INCREDIBLE IMAGES
FROM THIS DAY AND WE'RE GOING TO
SHOW YOU SOME OF THE LATEST.
That was ME...
the day I learned I had
to start insulin
for my type 2 diabetes.
ME...
thinking my only option was the
vial and syringe dad used.
And ME...
discovering once-daily
Levemir® FlexPen.
FlexPen® is prefilled.
Doesn't need
refrigeration
for up to
42 days.
No drawing from a vial.
Dial the exact dose.
Inject by pushing a button.
FlexPen® is insulin delivery...
MY way.
Levemir® (insulin detemir
[rDNA origin] injection)
is a long-acting insulin
used to control high blood sugar
in adults and children
with diabetes and is not
recommended to treat
diabetic ketoacidosis.
Do not use Levemir® if
you are allergic
to any of its ingredients.
The most common side effect
is low blood sugar,
which may cause
symptoms such as sweating,
shakiness, confusion,
and headache.
Severe low blood sugar can be
serious and life threatening.
Ask your healthcare provider
about alcohol use,
operating machinery, or driving.
Other possible side
effects include
injection site reactions.
Tell your healthcare provider
about all medicines you take
and all of your
medical conditions.
Get medical help right away
if you experience
serious allergic
reactions, such as body rash,
trouble with breathing, fast
heartbeat, or sweating.
With FlexPen®... say good night
to vial and syringe.
Ask your doctor about
Levemir® FlexPen.
Covered by
90% of insurance plans,
including Medicare.
Find your co-pay at
MyFlexPen.com.
AND HIS NEW BOSS TOLD HIM
TWO THINGS --
COOK WHAT YOU LOVE,
AND SAVE YOUR MONEY.
JOE DOESN'T KNOW IT YET,
BUT HE'LL WORK HIS WAY UP
FROM BUSSER TO WAITER TO CHEF
BEFORE OPENING A RESTAURANT
SPECIALIZING IN FISH AND GAME
FROM THE GREAT NORTHWEST.
HE'LL START INVESTING EARLY,
HE'LL FIND SOME GOOD PEOPLE
TO HELP GUIDE HIM,
AND HE'LL SET MONEY ASIDE
FROM HIS FIRST DAY OF WORK
TO HIS LAST,
WHICH ISN'T ROCKET SCIENCE.
IT'S JUST COMMON SENSE.
FROM TD AMERITRADE.
THEN I READ AN ARTICLE
ABOUT A STUDY THAT LOOKED
AT THE LONG TERM HEALTH BENEFITS
OF TAKING MULTIVITAMINS.
THEY USED CENTRUM SILVER
FOR THE STUDY...
SO I GUESS MY WIFE WAS RIGHT.
[ Male Announcer ] CENTRUM.
ALWAYS YOUR MOST COMPLETE.
TONIGHT, TRAGEDY AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, A SPECIAL
"20/20" ON ABC.
>>> NOW, SOME OF YOU WILL BE
LEAVING US, BUT OTHERS WE HOPE
YOU STAY WITH US FOR MORE OF OUR
SPECIAL ONE-HOUR OF "WORLD
NEWS."
AND A NOTE ABOUT LATER, WE'LL BE
ANCHORING A ONE-HOUR SPECIAL
EDITION OF "20/20," TRAGEDY AT
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, 10:00
P.M. TONIGHT.
AND NOW WE WANT TO LEAVE YOU
WITH SOME OF THOSE INCREDIBLE
IMAGES OF THIS DAY, FOR THOSE OF
YOU WHO WILL BE WITH US AGAIN,
WE'LL SEE YOU IN A FEW MINUTES.
FOR THE REST OF YOU, A GOOD
NIGHT.
♪
>> FROM ABC NEWS, THIS IS A
SPECIAL EDITION OF "WORLD NEWS"
WITH DIANE SAWYER, TRAGEDY AT
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
REPORTING FROM CONNECTICUT,
DIANE SAWYER.
>> GOOD EVENING, AND WE WELCOME
YOU BACK TO OUR SPECIAL,
ONE-HOUR EDITION OF "WORLD
NEWS," THE TRAGEDY AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
EARLY THIS MORNING A GUNMAN
OPENING FIRE AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, SMALL CHILDREN IN THE
CROSSFIRE.
FAMILIES DESPERATE FOR NEWS OF
THEIR CHILDREN.