SPECIAL DELIVERY FROM TWO-TIME
DAYTONA 500 CHAMPION
MICHAEL WALTRIP.
[ CROWD CHEERING ]
WE'RE NOT ONLY
HELPING THIS FAMILY,
WE'RE ALLOWING THIS FAMILY TO BE
ABLE TO HELP SO MANY OTHERS.
I JUST WISH THAT EVERY CHILD
HAS A FAMILY LIKE THIS,
BECAUSE NOBODY KNOWS HOW WE FEEL
WHEN WE BE TAKEN AWAY
FROM OUR OWN HOME.
I'M HAVING THE BEST CHRISTMAS
OF MY LIFE, GUYS!
[ Voice breaking ]
MY PRAYERS HAVE BEEN ANSWERED.
[ CROWD CHEERING ]
Ty: LISTEN,
MICHAEL, PAIGE, JILLIAN, ED,
DON'T YOU JUST LOVE
CHRISTMASTIME?
YES!
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
NOW, RIGHT NOW, WE'RE CRUISING
THROUGH NORTH CAROLINA,
ON OUR WAY TO A SMALL TOWN
CALLED LINCOLNTON...
NICE.
...TO SURPRISE
THE FRIDAY FAMILY.
IT'S JAMES AND DEVONDA
AND THEIR SEVEN KIDS.
TAKE A LOOK AT THIS,
AND YOU'LL SEE WHY WE'RE HERE.
THIS IS
GONNA BE GREAT.
HELLO, MY NAME IS JAMES,
AND THIS IS MY LOVELY WIFE,
DEVONDA.
WE HAVE AMAZING
CHILDREN --
JDIAH, WHO IS 13, IN MIDDLE
SCHOOL, AND OLIVIA, WHO IS 7.
I LOVE CHILDREN.
THAT'S WHERE MY HEART IS.
YEAH.
I USED TO WORK FOR THE CITY OF
LINCOLNTON AS A POLICE OFFICER,
[Voice breaking]
AND CHILDREN DON'T HAVE
ADVOCATES
TO SPEAK FOR THEM.
CHILDREN ARE BROUGHT INTO
THE WORLD WITHOUT A SAY.
SEVEN YEARS AGO, I'D SEEN
A CHILD ABUSED SO BAD
THAT THE CHILD'S FACE
HAD BEEN SCRATCHED
LITERALLY
ALL THE WAY DOWN.
AND I FIGURED, IF I COULDN'T
DO ANYTHING ON MY JOB
THAT WE COULD DO SOMETHING
AS HUSBAND AND WIFE.
DEVONDA AND I THOUGHT MAYBE
WE COULD REALLY JUST STEP IT UP
AND BECOME FOSTER PARENTS
OURSELVES.
SINCE THEN, WE'VE HAD 30
CHILDREN IN AND OUT OF OUR HOME.
I HAD BEEN
IN OTHER FOSTER FAMILIES,
BUT NO ONE WAS LIKE THE FRIDAYS.
THEY ALWAYS TOLD ME
THAT I CAN DO ANYTHING
IF I PUT MY MIND TO IT.
JUST A YEAR AGO, WE WERE ABLE
TO FOSTER A CHILD NAMED CHRIS.
WHEN HE CAME,
HE BROUGHT ALONG A VIDEO,
AND WE HAD NO IDEA THAT HE HAD
FOUR OTHER SIBLINGS.
MM-HMM.
Chris: I ALWAYS KNEW
THAT I WANTED TO STAY
WITH MY BROTHERS AND SISTERS,
BECAUSE I JUST LOVE THEM.
ALWAYS WANTED A HOUSE
I COULD JUST CALL HOME
AND A MOM AND DAD.
THAT'S ALL I WANTED.
Phyllis:
THESE CHILDREN ARE SO PRECIOUS.
AND A LITTLE FAMILY GROUP
LIKE THIS COMES TO CROSSNORE
WITH ONLY
THE CLOTHES ON THEIR BACK.
THEY'VE SORT OF BEEN PUSHED
THROUGH A NUMBER OF ORPHANAGES
AND FOSTER HOMES -- ALL FIVE
OF THE BROTHERS AND SISTERS.
THEY'VE JUST REALLY NEVER HAD
A SPACE OF THEIR OWN.
I THINK THE VIDEO MEANT TO CHRIS
THE ONLY CHANCE
OF HE AND HIS BROTHERS
AND SISTERS GETTING ADOPTED.
WE MADE A VOW
TO KEEP THE FAMILY TOGETHER.
AND WE MADE IT HAPPEN.
WE OFFICIALLY ADOPTED THE
FAB FIVE IN APRIL OF THIS YEAR.
NOW WE HAVE A TOTAL OF
NINE OF US IN THIS HOUSEHOLD.
AAH!
MY BEST THING --
LOVE TACKLING DAD.
London:
I LIKE GIVING MY MOM HUGS
BECAUSE SHE IS VERY PRETTY
AND SHE'S BEING NICE TO US.
Chris:
DEVONDA AND JAMES --
I ASKED IF I CAN CALL THEM
MOM AND DAD,
AND WHEN I ASKED THEM,
THEY SAID YES.
WHEN THE FAB FIVE FIRST COME
TO OUR HOUSE, IT WAS A SHOCK.
IT MEANT EVERYTHING
TIMES 7 NOW.
WE'D HAVE TO GO BUY
GROCERIES
THAT I THOUGHT WOULD LAST
FOR A WEEK,
THAT WOULD BE DONE
IN A DAY.
THE KIDS ARE INVOLVED
IN A LOT OF ACTIVITIES.
HEY!
I VOLUNTEERED TO BE THE
CHEERLEADER COACH, SO HERE I AM.
BEAT 'EM, BEAT 'EM, BEAT 'EM!
YAY! WHOO!
THIS IS
OUR FIRST CHRISTMAS
TOGETHER AS THE NEW
FRIDAY FAMILY,
AND WE LIKE TO HELP OUT
WITH THE COMMUNITY.
MY WIFE AND I STARTED
THE HOUSE OF HOPE
TO SUPPORT THE DEPARTMENT
OF SOCIAL SERVICES
AND THE FOSTER-CARE
DEPARTMENT.
THROUGH DONATIONS, WE'VE
BEEN ABLE TO PROVIDE ITEMS
SUCH AS TOILETRY ITEMS,
PERSONAL-CARE ITEMS
FOR FOSTER CHILDREN,
TO HELP FILL THEIR NEEDS.
"WHY."
"WHY..."
James: ABOUT SIX MONTHS AGO,
I WAS AN ENGINEER
FOR A LOCAL
ENGINEERING COMPANY.
THE ECONOMY HIT AND REALLY
AFFECTED US FINANCIALLY.
MY WIFE HAD TO TAKE
A PART-TIME JOB
JUST SO WE COULD
MAKE ENDS MEET.
SINCE THEN,
WE'RE UNABLE TO AFFORD
THE HOUSE OF HOPE BUILDING
THAT WE WERE RENTING.
JAMES AND I ARE ABLE TO GIVE
OUR CHILDREN
ALL THE LOVE
THAT THEY NEED.
BUT RIGHT NOW,
WE CAN'T GIVE OUR CHILDREN
THE HOUSE THAT THEY NEED.
WE CLOSED IN OUR CARPORT
TO ACCOMMODATE THE FAB FIVE.
BECAUSE IT WAS OUR CARPORT,
THERE'S NO INSULATION.
THE ROOMS ARE JUST CRAMPED.
EVERY CLOSET IS MAXED OUT.
ONE BATHROOM IN THE HALLWAY,
AND WE HAVE OTHER ISSUES
WITH OUR PLUMBING,
WITH OUR FOUNDATION.
WE HAVE A CRACK THAT GOES
THROUGH THE FLOOR OF OUR HOUSE.
Devonda:
THE ENTIRE ADDITION IS SETTLING.
WATER IS COMING THROUGH
THE HOUSE,
WHICH IS CAUSING OUR WALLS
TO ACTUALLY COME APART.
[ Voice breaking ]
WHEN WE BROUGHT CHRIS AND THEM
TO OUR HOME,
THE FABULOUS FIVE,
WE PROMISED THEM
TO PROVIDE FOR THEM.
WE'RE AT THE POINT WHERE
ALL OUR RESOURCES ARE EXHAUSTED.
WE'RE GONNA CONTINUE TO LOVE
THEM AND PROVIDE FOR THEM,
BUT, "EXTREME MAKEOVER,"
WE DESPERATELY NEED YOUR HELP.
WE DESPERATELY NEED YOU
TO COME AND HELP US.
Girls:
[ Rhythmically ] ♪ TY
[ CLAPPING RHYTHMICALLY ]
♪ COME
♪ AND SEE US
♪ MOVE THAT BUTT
WHOO!
INCREDIBLE FAMILY.
YEAH, THEY WERE GREAT.
OKAY, SO,
HERE'S THE THING.
CHRISTMAS IS A REALLY BIG DEAL
TO THE FRIDAY FAMILY, OKAY?
AND EVERY YEAR, THEY GO TO
A TREE FARM TO PICK OUT A TREE.
WELL, THAT'S WHEN
WE'RE GONNA SURPRISE THE FAMILY.
WELL, HOW DO YOU KNOW
THEY'RE THERE?
WELL, AN ELF TOLD ME.
YEAH.
OH.
SO, WHAT DO YOU SAY, PEOPLE?
CAN WE DO THIS?!
YEAH!
BRING IT IN THERE, PEOPLE.
ARE YOU WITH ME?
WE'RE WITH YOU.
YES.
WELL, THEN LET'S...
All: DO IT!
WHOO!
Ed: NOTHING GIVES ME
GREATER PLEASURE
THAN WHEN WE ARE AMBUSHING
OUR FAMILIES
"EXTREME MAKEOVER" STYLE.
Henry: HEY, TY.
HEY, HENRY.
HOW ARE YOU, MAN?
ARE THE FAMILY UP THERE?
THEY ARE.
THEY'RE RIGHT BACK UP YONDER.
Ed: THE FRIDAY FAMILY
HAVE GOT NO IDEA
THERE ARE FIVE STEALTHY
DESIGNERS CREEPING UP ON THEM
THROUGH THE OVERGROWN GROWTH
OF THE CHRISTMAS-TREE FARM.
THEY'RE GONNA GET
THE SURPRISE OF THEIR LIFE.
Devonda:
YEAH, THIS IS A GOOD ONE.
GOOD MORNING, FRIDAY FAMILY!
[ ALL CHEERING ]
HEY!
WELL, HELLO,
FRIDAY FAMILY.
HI!         HI!
HI!                          HI!
James: OH, MAN.
[ SNIFFLES ]
Y'ALL JUST DON'T KNOW, MAN.
WHY ARE YOU CRYING
RIGHT NOW?
Devonda:
I'M SO THANKFUL.
SOMEBODY WILL BE ABLE TO SEE
THAT WHAT WE DO,
THEY WILL BE ABLE TO DO
THE SAME THING
AND GIVE SOME KIDS
A STABLE ENVIRONMENT,
A PLACE THAT THEY'LL FEEL
LOVE AND UNDERSTANDING
AND BE ABLE TO GROW UP
AND KNOW
THAT THEY DON'T HAVE TO WORRY
ABOUT GOING TO A FACILITY
OR GETTING SPLIT UP AND NOT KNOW
WHERE THEIR SIBLINGS ARE.
WELL, I THINK WE'VE GOT
A PRETTY BIG CHRISTMAS SURPRISE
FOR YOU GUYS --
A LITTLE PRESENT.
OKAY.
I'M SURE
THAT'S A PERFECT TREE
FOR, LIKE,
THE HOUSE YOU HAVE NOW.
WE'RE THINKING
YOU MIGHT WANT SOMETHING
A LITTLE BIGGER
FOR THE NEW ONE.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
WE CAN DO THAT.
YEAH?
WELL, LET'S GO PICK OUT A TREE.
COME ON!
ALL RIGHT! WHOO!
HA HA!
Girl: YEAH!
Devonda: OKAY!
YOU SEE ANY TREES
YOU LIKE?
OH, WHAT ABOUT THAT ONE?
THAT ONE.
THAT ONE?
Michael: SO, WE'RE CRUISING
THROUGH THE LOT,
AND I SEE THIS TREE
THAT'S LIKE 18 FEET TALL.
YOU KNOW?
WE'RE BUILDING A BIG HOUSE.
LET'S GO BIG, RIGHT?
IT'S THE HOLIDAYS.
I THINK WE'RE GONNA NEED
SOMETHING BIGGER THAN THIS.
YEAH.
WE'RE GONNA NEED
A BIGGER SAW.
HEY, HENRY!
WE'LL TAKE THIS BIG ONE.
THAT'S A GOOD CHOICE.
Woman: THIS?
YEAH.
TIMBER!
WHOA-OA!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
SO, GUYS, HERE'S WHAT I THINK
WE OUGHT TO DO.
WE'RE GONNA STRAP THIS
ON THE BUS.
LET'S TAKE A BUS RIDE
AND GO CHECK OUT
WHERE YOU GUYS
HAVE BEEN LIVING.
ALL RIGHT!
Ty: I THINK SOMETIMES
WE TAKE FOR GRANTED
HOW AMAZING IT IS
TO SPEND TIME WITH OUR FAMILIES,
TO KNOW THAT THEY'RE
THERE FOR US,
TO KNOW THAT THEY CARE,
'CAUSE AS YOU LOOK AT THE FACES
OF THIS FAMILY,
YOU REALIZE SOME OF THESE KIDS,
THEY NEVER REALLY HAD THAT.
THAT'S WHY IT'S IMPORTANT
THIS WEEK
THAT WE GIVE THIS FAMILY
AS MUCH AS WE CAN,
BECAUSE THEY'RE SHOWING
OTHER FAMILIES
HOW IT SHOULD BE DONE.
♪ JINGLE BELLS, JINGLE BELLS,
JINGLE ALL THE WAY ♪
♪ OH, WHAT FUN IT IS TO RIDE
IN A ONE-HORSE OPEN SLEIGH ♪
♪ HEY!
Hey buddy, I bet Mom
would love this, huh?
Jack?
Jaaack?
Jaaack?!
Jack?!
Looks good
ladies!
Jack!
Come on,
stop the car.
JACK!
No, no, no, no, no!
The only thing more surprising
than finding the
perfect gifts..
Niice.
...is where you find them.
How did you know?
I had a little help.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
TO PRACTICE MATH
MORE?
I LOVE MATH!
BUT TWO iPADS
MEANS TWO DATA PLANS?
THAT'S CRAZY.
MAYBE NOT.
WITH AT&T MOBILE SHARE,
ADDING AN iPAD
IS JUST $10 A MONTH.
BUT HONESTLY, MOM AND DAD'S LOVE
IS ALL I REALLY NEED.
WE SHOULD KEEP THESE
FOR US.
WE SHOULD KEEP THESE.
WHAT?!
[ Male Announcer ]
AT&T MOBILE SHARE.
ADD AN iPAD
FOR JUST $10 A MONTH.
ONE PLAN. UP TO 10 DEVICES.
AT&T. RETHINK POSSIBLE.
Ty:
COME ON, EVERYBODY.
COME ON OUT.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATION ]
THERE YOU GO.
PERFECT.
DEVONDA AND JAMES ARE WHAT YOU'D
CALL REALLY INCREDIBLE PARENTS.
THEY'VE OPENED UP THEIR HEARTS
AND THEIR HOME TO SO MANY KIDS.
NOW THEY'VE ALSO
RECENTLY ADOPTED
FIVE SIBLINGS
THEY CALL THE FAB FIVE.
AND SO NOW THEY'VE GOT
A VERY LARGE FAMILY,
BUT THEY'RE LIVING IN A HOME
THAT'S STILL VERY SMALL.
DESIGN TEAM, WHY DON'T
YOU GUYS TAKE THE KIDS,
GO INSIDE THE HOUSE,
TAKE A LOOK AROUND,
AND WE'LL ALL MEET UP LATER.
OKAY?
LET'S DO IT.
Devonda:
COME ON, GUYS. OKAY.
Michael: CHECK IT OUT.
WANT TO SEE THE HOUSE, BUDDY.
WHAT'S ALL, UH, WHAT'S ALL
THIS STUFF WITH THE TARPS?
James:
IT'S MERCHANDISE THAT WE RECEIVE
THROUGH DONATIONS FOR OUR
HOUSE OF HOPE RESOURCE CENTER,
AND WE REDISTRIBUTE
TO THE COMMUNITY.
AND WHAT WE TRY TO DO
IS TO CATER TO FOSTER FAMILIES.
WE DID HAVE A PLACE BEFORE
THAT WE KIND OF
RAN OUR PROGRAM THROUGH.
OH, OKAY.
AND THE RENT
WAS JUST TOO HIGH.
WE WASN'T ABLE TO...
TO PAY THE RENT?
YEAH.
...BRING REVENUES IN
TO PAY THE RENT.
SO, YOU GUYS ARE PAYING RENT
TO A PLACE
TO JUST BE ABLE
TO STORE STUFF
THAT YOU COULD
GIVE TO PEOPLE FOR FREE.
ABSOLUTELY.
YEAH.
IT SAYS SO MUCH
ABOUT DEVONDA AND JAMES
THAT THEY NOT ONLY
CARE FOR THESE KIDS,
THEY CARE ABOUT THE PROCESS
SO THAT MORE KIDS
CAN FIND HOMES,
MORE KIDS
CAN BECOME PART OF FAMILIES.
AND WHEN THEY GET THERE,
THEY'VE GOT THEIR SUPPLIES
TO REALLY BE CARED FOR.
SO I THINK, THIS WEEK,
IT'S IMPORTANT THAT
WE REALLY FIGURE OUT
A SPACE FOR THEM TO BE ABLE
TO PUT ALL THIS STUFF.
WHEN DID YOU GUYS MEET
FOR THE FIRST TIME?
SEVENTH GRADE.
RIGHT BEFORE
THE SPRING DANCE.
MM-HMM.
I ASKED HIM OUT.
NO, NO,
I ASKED HER OUT.
[ LAUGHS ]
BEING LUCKY ENOUGH TO FIND, YOU
KNOW, SOMEONE YOU REALLY LOVE,
THAT YOU WANT TO SPEND THE REST
OF YOUR LIFE WITH IS ONE THING,
BUT THAT COMMITMENT, YOU KNOW,
TO BECOME A FOSTER PARENT,
WHAT MADE YOU
WANT TO DO THAT?
JUST 'CAUSE YOU --
IT'S THE LOVE.
CHILDREN HAVE NO SAY.
IT'S NOT THEIR FAULT.
WE OPEN OUR HOME
JUST FOR THEM TO RECOGNIZE
THEIR FULL POTENTIAL.
OH, YEAH,
THEY GONNA HAVE THAT.
WHAT WE'VE
TRIED TO INSTILL IN THEM
IS TO TREAT OTHERS WELL
AND DO THE RIGHT THING,
STAY IN SCHOOL, APPLY YOURSELF,
FAMILY, AND THAT,
AND JUST
THE WHOLE SPIRIT OF GIVING.
THAT'S JUST ALWAYS
MEANT SOMETHING TO ME.
SO, THIS WILL BE THE FIRST
CHRISTMAS TOGETHER AS A FAMILY?
YEAH.
AS FRIDAYS, MM-HMM.
AS FRIDAYS.
I LOVE YOU GUYS' NAMES --
FRIDAYS.
I MEAN, HOW MANY TIMES
DO YOU USE -- COME ON --
"THANK GOD IT'S FRIDAY"?
"THANK GOD IT'S FRIDAY."
"THANK GOD
IT'S FRIDAY," YEAH.
[ LAUGHTER ]
Jillian: MICHAEL.
DOES IT GET
A LITTLE BIT CROWDED IN HERE?
Jillian: THIS IS THE FIRST
CHRISTMAS THAT THE FRIDAYS
ARE GONNA BE ABLE TO SPEND
AS AN OFFICIAL FAMILY.
IT'S A HUGE FAMILY NOW.
IT'S VERY OBVIOUS THAT
THE FRIDAYS NEED MORE SPACE.
SO, WHO DO YOU
SHARE THIS ROOM WITH?
LONDON.
IS IT HARD TO,
ALL OF A SUDDEN,
GET FIVE NEW
BROTHERS AND SISTERS?
Paige: I GOT A CHANCE TO SPEND
SOME TIME WITH OLIVIA.
YOU KNOW,
SHE WAS JUST ONE OF TWO.
IS THIS
YOUR FAVORITE BOOK?
AND THEN, ALL OF A SUDDEN, SHE
GETS FIVE BROTHERS AND SISTERS,
AND SHE'S ADJUSTED SO WELL.
SHE'S KIND OF THE BIG SIS
TO ALL OF THEM,
EVEN THOUGH SHE ISN'T
OLDER THAN ALL OF THEM.
LOOK HOW COOL!
IS THIS CINDY LOU WHO?
SO, CAN I CALL YOU
OLIVIA LOU WHO?
MM-HMM.
OKAY.
JDIAH, OH, SO, YOU
HAVE A PROBLEM THERE
WITH YOUR SHOULDER.
YOU DROPPED IT.
SEE, I PLAY MORE FOOTBALL.
KEEP YOUR SHOULDER STRAIGHT
AND FOLLOW THROUGH.
I SHOULDN'T BE THIS MUCH
OUT OF SHAPE FOR 22.
[ GRUNTS ] AW. OH!
OH, THAT'S THE ONE.
[ Breathlessly ] OKAY.
HOW NICE IS IT TO HAVE
A BIGGER BROTHER NOW?
IT'S REAL GOOD, 'CAUSE
HE CAN TEACH ME A LOT OF THINGS.
AND IT'S BETTER JUST NOT TO BE
THE ONLY BOY IN THE HOUSE.
CHRIS, WHAT DOES HE
USUALLY DO WITH HIS FREE TIME
IF HE'S NOT
PLAYING BASKETBALL?
PLAYING VIDEO GAMES.
OH, REALLY?
I COME HOME,
FINISH MY HOMEWORK,
DO MY CHORES,
THEN PLAY VIDEO GAMES.
SO, YOU THINK
YOU'RE PRETTY GOOD?
YEAH.
I MEAN, JUST WHUPPED
YOUR BROTHER AT BASKETBALL.
WHOA! WHOA!
OH, MY GOD!
DID ANYONE SEE THAT THAT?!
ANYONE?
I NOTICED THERE'S
CABINET DOORS ON THE FLOOR.
YEAH, YEAH.
SO, THINGS ARE SORT OF
STARTING TO...
OPEN AND CLOSE AND OPEN AND
CLOSE, AND I'M COOKING FOR NINE.
AND I NOTICED OVER HERE
IS, LIKE, A LITTLE DESK.
YEAH, WE GOT A DESK
RIGHT HERE,
AND THAT'S WHAT WE KIND OF USE,
COMPUTER AREA.
SO, THIS IS IT?
THIS IS IT.
FOR SEVEN KIDS?
RIGHT NOW, YOU GOT SEVEN KIDS
LIVING IN THIS HOUSE
THAT ARE 15 AND YOUNGER.
THEY'RE GOOD KIDS AND VERY
WELL-BEHAVED, BUT THEY'RE KIDS.
THEY WANT TO PLAY.
CLIMBING ON -- YOU GUYS
ARE CLIMBING ON THAT?!
THAT'S A TREE.
THAT'S OUR CLUBHOUSE!
I THINK ABOUT EVERYTHING THEY'VE
BEEN THROUGH IN THE PAST.
I KNOW IT HASN'T BEEN EASY,
AND I KNOW IT'S BEEN ROUGH
AND THEY HAVEN'T HAD
ANYTHING OF THEIR OWN.
WE WANT TO GIVE THEM
THOSE THINGS
BECAUSE THAT'S
WHAT JAMES AND DEVONDA WANT.
THEY WANT TO GIVE THEM SPACE.
THEY WANT TO GIVE THEM
ROOM TO STUDY
AND TO PLAY AND TO LEARN
AND TO GROW.
AND THAT JUST CAN'T HAPPEN
IN THE HOUSE THEY'RE IN.
ARE ALL OF THESE
YOUR DOLLS?
YEAH.
YEAH?
♪ DOO-DOO-DOO DOO DOO
HEY.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
LONDON.
BABY DOLL.
THAT'S VERY HIGH-FASHION.
THANK YOU.
LET ME SEE.
HOLD IT UP.
CARLY, WHO DO YOU LOOK UP TO
WITH FASHION?
MY MOM.
YOUR MOM?
YEAH.
NICE!
WHOO-HOO!
OKAY, LUKE, DO YOU PREFER PENCIL
OR DO YOU PREFER PEN?
PENCIL.
ME TOO. ALL THE GREAT ARTISTS
LOVE A GOOD PENCIL.
ARE YOU LOOKING FORWARD
TO A NEW HOUSE?
MM-HMM.
THIS IS WHERE
YOU SAY TO ME,
"I'M LOOKING FORWARD
TO NOT SHARING A ROOM
WITH ME BIG BROTHER CHRIS,
'CAUSE HE SMELLS."
[ GIGGLING ]
I MEAN, IT'S JUST --
IT'S NOT RIGHT.
YOU SHOULD NEVER TALK ABOUT
YOUR BIG BROTHER LIKE THAT.
I WROTE THIS.
THIS?
IT SAYS "MY LIFE."
"AT THE AGE OF NINE YEARS OLD,
I WAS TAKEN FROM MY PARENTS."
WOW.
YOU MIND READING
SOME OF IT TO ME?
YES.
OKAY.
"WHEN I WAS GROWING UP,
I DID NOT HAVE A LOT.
"I NEVER WENT TO SCHOOL.
I STAYED HOME.
"I NEVER THOUGHT ABOUT
GOING TO COLLEGE,
BUT NOW I KNOW WHAT I WANT TO BE
WHEN I GROW UP."
Jillian:
KAMAYA IS ACTUALLY WRITING
A BIT OF AN AUTOBIOGRAPHY
OF HER LIFE.
YOU KNOW,
SHE'S BEEN THROUGH A LOT.
WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT
CHRIS AND KAMAYA,
BEFORE THEY WERE ADOPTED
BY THE FRIDAYS,
REALLY WERE THE PARENTAL FIGURES
IN THAT FAMILY OF KIDS.
"I WONDER WHERE I'M GOING TO GO
FROM HERE.
"I KNOW WHERE I DON'T WANT TO BE
IS IN JAIL.
"WHEN MY STEPDAD WENT TO JAIL,
I CHANGED.
"I WENT FROZEN.
"IN MY LIFE, A LOT OF PEOPLE
TOLD ME THEY CARED ABOUT ME,
BUT WHEN I NEED SOMETHING
OR I'M DOWN, THEY'RE NOT THERE."
AND THAT'S IT.
WOW.
THAT MUST BE REALLY HARD.
GIVE ME A HUG.
ARE THERE ANY DREAMS
YOU GUYS HAVE FOR YOURSELVES?
YEAH.
WHEN WE -- WHEN WE STARTED
WITH THE CHILDREN,
WE KIND OF
PUT THOSE ON HOLD.
OKAY, WELL,
IF YOU COULD GO ANYWHERE,
WHAT KIND OF PLACE
WOULD YOU LIKE TO GO, YOU THINK?
CARIBBEAN.
SOMEWHERE RELAXED.
[ Chuckling ]
YEAH, SOMETHING JUST -- YEAH.
YEAH.
NO WORRIES.
YEAH, THE CARIBBEAN DEFINITELY
HAS THAT NO-WORRIES FEEL TO IT.
[ LAUGHS ] YEAH, YEAH.
YEAH, NO WORRIES.
ABSOLUTELY.
SO, WHAT DO YOU GUYS LIKE TO DO
AS A FAMILY?
WE HAVE A FAMILY MOVIE NIGHT,
WE HAVE A FAMILY MEETING.
AND WE DO THAT EVEN WITH DINNER.
WE ALL TRY TO GATHER
AROUND THE TABLE,
BECAUSE WE KNOW THAT
THAT'S NEVER BEEN
THE TYPE OF ENVIRONMENT
THEY HAVE BEEN USED TO.
BECAUSE THEY MOVE AROUND SO MUCH
FROM FOSTER HOME TO FOSTER HOME,
THAT'S WHAT
THEY WERE USED TO.
MM-HMM.
"OKAY, WE'RE HERE FOR NOW,
BUT HOW MUCH LONGER
IS IT GONNA BE
TILL I MOVE AGAIN?"
AND WE WANTED TO TAKE
THAT THOUGHT
AWAY FROM THEM IMMEDIATELY,
AND SO WE'RE FAMILY NOW.
RIGHT.
YOU KNOW?
YEAH.
AND HAVE THEY TALKED
ABOUT, LIKE,
WISHING THEY COULD HELP
SOME OF THE OTHER KIDS?
OH, YEAH. OH, YEAH.
YEAH, THEY HAVE.
KAMAYA WANTS TO BE
A FOSTER PARENT.
TO KNOW THAT THESE KIDS
ARE GROWING UP,
THAT THEY'RE GONNA
WANT TO GO BACK
AND GIVE BACK TO THE SAME SYSTEM
THAT THEY CAME OUT OF,
TO MAKE IT A BETTER PLACE TO BE,
IF WE CAN HELP YOU GUYS IN
THAT WAY, WE'RE GLAD TO DO IT.
WE'RE GLAD YOU'RE HERE.
LET'S GRAB EVERYBODY.
I THINK IT'S ALREADY
GOTTEN DARK OUTSIDE.
OKAY.
OKAY?
BUT WE'RE GONNA SEND YOU GUYS
OFF ON VACATION.
ALL RIGHT.
YEAH, ABSOLUTELY.
LET'S GATHER
EVERYBODY UP.
[ CHILDREN CHEERING ]
OKAY, EVERYBODY, COME ON OUT!
YOU GUYS SEE THE BUS
ALL LIT UP?
OH, MY GOD.
CHECK THIS OUT!
OH, WOW!
OH, MY GOSH.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
WHOO!
YEAH!
SO, FRIDAY FAMILY,
I'D LIKE YOU TO MEET THE PEOPLE
WHO ACTUALLY WILL BE BUILDING
YOUR HOUSE THIS WEEK --
FRANK HEREDA, WADE MILLER,
AND THE WHOLE CREW
FROM BELLAMY HOMES!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
YOU GUYS HAVE ANYTHING
YOU WANT TO SAY TO THE FAMILY?
I TRULY DON'T THINK THAT YOU
KNOW HOW SPECIAL YOU TRULY ARE.
YOU KNOW, YOU'VE CHANGED
THE LIVES OF YOUR CHILDREN,
YOU'VE CHANGED THE LIVES
OF EVERYTHING IN THE COMMUNITY.
YOU'VE ALSO
CHANGED ME ALREADY.
WE'RE GONNA GIVE YOU GUYS
A FANTASTIC GIFT
THAT IS GONNA MAKE A DIFFERENCE
IN YOUR FAMILY.
SO WE HOPE
THAT THIS IS JUST
THE BEST CHRISTMAS EVER
FOR YOU GUYS.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
KIM EVANS, COME FORWARD,
IF YOU WILL.
WHY DON'T YOU TELL US
HOW YOU KNOW THE FRIDAYS.
Kim: WELL, I'M KIMBERLY EVANS,
AND I GO TO NORTH CAROLINA A&T.
I WAS A FOSTER CHILD
OF THE FRIDAYS.
THE STUFF
THAT THEY DO FOR ME IS...
[ SOBS ]
I JUST WISH THAT EVERY CHILD
HAS A FAMILY LIKE THIS,
BECAUSE NOBODY KNOWS HOW WE FEEL
WHEN WE BE TAKEN AWAY
FROM OUR OWN HOME.
SO I'M VERY PROUD
TO BE WITH Y'ALL.
James:
WE'RE PROUD TO HAVE YOU.
[ APPLAUSE ]
Paige:
THE FRIDAY FAMILY, TO ME,
IS THE TRUE SPIRIT OF CHRISTMAS,
THE TRUE SPIRIT OF GIVING.
AND THEY'VE FOSTERED
OVER 30 KIDS OVER THE YEARS.
AND THERE ARE SO MANY PEOPLE
OUT THERE
THAT THEIR LIVES
HAVE BEEN CHANGED
BY THE LOVE
THAT JAMES AND DEVONDA HAVE.
I MEAN,
WHAT IS A BIGGER GIFT THAN THAT?
SO, WHILE WE'RE GONNA BE
BUILDING YOU GUYS A HOUSE
THIS WEEK,
YOU GUYS GET TO GO ON VACATION.
CONSIDERING IT'S ALSO
SORT OF THE HOLIDAY SEASON,
WE THOUGHT WE'D SEND YOU
SOMEPLACE WARM.
[ LAUGHTER ]
YOU GUYS ARE GOING
TO BEACHES RESORT IN JAMAICA!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
SO, LET'S GET YOU GUYS
IN THE LIMO!
RIGHT THROUGH HERE!
COME ON!
[ CROWD CHEERING ]
COME ON. THAT'S RIGHT.
[ CARIBBEAN MUSIC PLAYS ]
WHAT'S SO IMPORTANT
ABOUT THIS WEEK
IS THAT WE'RE ALLOWING
THIS FAMILY
TO BE ABLE TO HELP
SO MANY OTHERS.
THIS IS ABOUT GIVING KIDS
EVERYTHING THEY NEED
TO HAVE A CHANCE AT LIFE.
THE FRIDAY FAMILY
NOT ONLY GIVES THEM A CHANCE,
IT LETS THEM KNOW THAT THEY CAN
BE ANYTHING THEY WANT TO BE.
ENJOY JAMAICA, GUYS!
HAVE A GOOD TIME!
[ "JOY TO THE WORLD" PLAYS ]
IT'S A R-REGGAE CHRISTMAS!
LET'S GET BUSY!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
IT'S NOT FOR COLDS,
IT'S NOT FOR PAIN,
IT'S JUST FOR SLEEP.
BECAUSE SLEEP
IS A BEAUTIFUL THING.
♪
ZZZQUIL,
THE NON-HABIT FORMING SLEEP-AID
FROM THE MAKERS OF NYQUIL.
ZZZQUIL,
Bye!
Santa, we made a video for
your trip!
Yeah, you can watch it on your
sleigh!
OK!
Here you go.
Aw, thanks elves.
I also made you a video.
You are so sweet.
But you probably shouldn't watch
it on the sleigh.
Say goodbye to Santa boys!
Bye!
Good bye Santa!
Exclusively at AT&T, buy any
Samsung Galaxy smartphone,
get up to $100 off a second
Samsung Galaxy device.
YAY!
COME GET INTO BED.
THIS IS A STORY
ABOUT JINGLE THE HUSKY PUP.
AND JINGLE WAS A GOOD DOG.
RUFF! RUFF!
JINGLE LOVED TO BARK
HELLO.
RUFF! RUFF! RUFF! RUFF!
JINGLE EVEN LOVED TO SING.
RUFF! RUFF! RUFF! RUFF! RUFF!
JINGLE!
LET'S READ THE BOOK
TO HIM.
JINGLE, STAY.
AND JINGLE DID.
RUFF! RUFF!
[ Female announcer ]
Hallmark Interactive
Story Buddies.
WHEN YOU READ KEY WORDS,
JINGLE RESPONDS.
CAN BUILDFemale announcer ]
Hallmark Interactive
Story Buddies.
THE FRIDAY FAMILY A NEW HOUSE,
WE HAVE TO GET RID OF
THE OLD ONE.
AND SINCE IT IS THE HOLIDAY
SEASON, IT'S ALL ABOUT GIVING.
SO WE DECIDED TO SAVE AS MUCH
OF THE OLD HOUSE AS POSSIBLE
AND DONATE THOSE MATERIALS
TO FAMILIES
WHO CAN REALLY USE THEM.
AND IF WE ARE GONNA DEMO
THE HOUSE, WELL, THIS WEEK,
WE'LL ACTUALLY
BE ABLE TO DO SOMETHING
THAT I'VE ALWAYS WANTED TO DO.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATION ]
READY TO HAVE FUN?
YEAH.
James:
OH, A CARIBBEAN-ISLAND VACATION
WAS A DREAM VACATION
FOR ALL THE CHILDREN,
TO GET TO DO THINGS THAT THEY
PROBABLY WOULD NEVER HAVE DONE.
LONDON,
COME BUILD A SANDCASTLE.
OKAY.
ESPECIALLY FOR THE FAB FIVE.
I DON'T THINK,
AT ANY POINT IN TIME,
THEY WOULD IMAGINE
BEING WHISKED AWAY TO JAMAICA.
[ GASPS ]
Kamaya: MY FAVORITE PART WAS
RIDING HORSES AT THE BEACH.
WHEN WE FIRST GOT THERE,
AND I SEEN THE HORSE,
I WAS LIKE, "UNH-UNH,
I'M NOT DOING THIS, NO."
AND THEN, LIKE,
WHEN I GOT ON IT, IT WAS FUN.
WHOO!
THIS IS FUN, Y'ALL.
Ty:
HELLO, FRIDAY FAMILY.
HI, TY!     HI, TY!
HI, TY!                  HI, TY!
THIS IS GONNA BE
AN INCREDIBLE WEEK.
AND WE FIGURE, SINCE
THIS IS THE SEASON OF GIVING,
WHY NOT DO IT TO THE SOUNDS
OF CLASSIC CHRISTMAS CAROLS?
SIT BACK AND ENJOY OUR
VERY FIRST CHRISTMAS ALBUM --
"A HOLLY JOLLY DEMO"...
OH, MY GOD!
James: OH, MY GOODNESS!
...FEATURING FAVORITES LIKE
"IT'S STARTING TO LOOK
A LOT LIKE DEMO,"
"ALL I WANT FOR CHRISTMAS
IS A 2x4,"
"FROSTY,
THE FORKLIFT OPERATOR,"
AND FOR OUR LATIN FRIENDS,
"FELIZ NAVIDEMO,"
AND, OF COURSE,
THE INSTANT SENSATION
YOU'LL ALL BE SINGING
FOR CHRISTMASES TO COME,
"GOD REST YE,
OLD FRIDAY HOUSE."
[ FAMILY SCREAMING ]
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
James: IT'S CRAZY.
SINGING THE CHRISTMAS CAROLS
WHILE THEY WERE
TEARING DOWN OUR HOUSE.
STILL WAS GREAT TO SEE,
BECAUSE I KNEW
THAT WAS JUST THE START
OF WHAT WAS YET TO COME.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
SO, THERE YOU HAVE IT -- OUR
FIRST-EVER HOLIDAY DEMO ALBUM.
THAT IS AWESOME.
[ LAUGHTER ]
SO, GUYS,
HAVE A GREAT TIME ON VACATION.
AND MERRY CHRISTMAS.
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
WHOO!
[ SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
IT'S SO GOOD TO SEE
THE FRAMING GOING IN,
BECAUSE THIS HOUSE
IS GONNA BE REALLY SPECIAL,
NOT ONLY TO THE FAMILY,
BUT ESPECIALLY THESE KIDS.
THEY'D NOT ONLY NEVER HAD
REALLY A HOME OF THEIR OWN,
BUT THEY'VE NEVER HAD
A ROOM OF THEIR OWN,
AND WE ALL
TAKE THAT FOR GRANTED.
NOW, I HAD TO SHARE A ROOM
WITH MY BROTHER
WHEN I WAS LITTLE,
AND IT WASN'T A LOT OF FUN.
HE USED TO PUT DIRTY SOCKS
IN MY FACE
WHILE I WAS SLEEPING,
AND IT MADE ME SORT OF SICK.
THESE KIDS NEVER REALLY HAD
THAT FEELING
OF HAVING A ROOM OF THEIR OWN,
AND THESE GUYS
ARE MAKING IT HAPPEN.
SO, WE'RE OFF TO A GREAT START.
WE'RE WORKING ON CARLY'S ROOM.
AND SHE LOVES DRESSES
AND CLOTHES AND SHOPPING.
THE THING IS,
THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
SHE'S GONNA HAVE
HER OWN SPACE,
SO WE REALLY WANT TO MAKE IT
SO, SO, SO, SO SPECIAL.
Jillian: CARLY LOVES CLOTHES,
SO I WANT TO MAKE SURE
HER ROOM LOOKS LIKE A BEAUTIFUL,
COUTURE, HIGH-END BOUTIQUE.
SUNGLASSES. RIGHT?
I'M GONNA USE
CLOTHES AND ACCESSORIES
AS A PART OF THE DECOR PACKAGE.
UH, HELLO.
PERFECT.
Woman: YES!
HEY, PAIGE.
HEY.
WHAT ARE YOU WORKING ON?
I'M FRUSTRATED!
I AM WORKING ON
OLIVIA'S ROOM.
OH, GREAT.
SHE LOVES "HOW THE GRINCH
STOLE CHRISTMAS!"
SO I WANT EVERYTHING TO BE
FUNKY AND FUN AND FRESH.
AND AS YOU CAN SEE,
I'VE MESSED UP MANY TIMES.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
NOW I NEED MORE PAPER.
YOU'LL GET IT.
JUST KEEP WORKING ON IT.
IT'S FRUSTRATING!
YOU'RE GOOD AT THIS STUFF.
MICHAEL?
YEAH?
I KNEW YOU WOULD
GET THIS RIGHT.
I'LL GET THIS STARTED
IN THE SHOP RIGHT AWAY.
THIS LOOKS AWESOME!
BUT -- BUT THAT'S NOT --
THAT'S NOT WHAT I DID.
THAT ONE LOOKS --
NO, TAKE THAT.
THAT'S THE ONE.
JUST PUT --
WHAT ARE YOU
WORKING ON, SON?
WELL, LITTLE LUKE
WANTS TO BE A CARTOONIST,
AND HE LOVES
DRAWING CARTOONS.
SO A LOCAL CARTOON DRAWER
DREW UP THESE AMAZING
CARICATURES OF LUKE.
I NEED SOME CHRISTMAS MAGIC
TO TRY AND MAKE THEM COME ALIVE.
I THINK I CAN HELP YOU
WITH THAT.
YEAH, BUDDY,
UNLESS YOU KNOW MAGIC...
HO HO HO HO HO
HO HO HO HO HO.
I KNEW YOU WERE REAL!
I TOLD EVERYONE
YOU WERE REAL!
WHOO! NICE CAR.
OOH, THIS IS REALLY --
OOH, OOH.
THAT IS US, FOR SURE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
WOW.
"DEAREST DESIGN TEAM,
HAPPY HOLIDAYS.
"TAKE THIS SILVER SLEIGH TO THE
BELMONT DRIVE-IN MOVIE THEATER,
"WHERE YOUR CHALLENGE AWAITS.
LOVE, TY."
UH-OH.
MICHAEL, JILLIAN, ED!
OKAY, "FRIDAY DOUBLE FEATURE,"
BELMONT DRIVE-IN.
Ed: NICE.
YEP, WE'RE
IN THE RIGHT PLACE.
BEAUTIFUL.
YES!
LET'S GO.
I'M GETTING
THE POPCORN, GANG.
Michael: I USED TO GO
TO THE DRIVE-IN MOVIES
ALL THE TIME
WHEN I WAS A KID.
YOU DON'T SEE THEM ANYMORE.
AS WE PULL INTO THIS
OLD, CLASSIC DRIVE-IN THEATER,
THERE WERE A BUNCH
OF CLASSIC CARS AROUND.
THIS IS GOOD, THIS IS GOOD,
THIS IS GOOD.
AND I GUESS WE MISSED
THE FIRST MOVIE,
'CAUSE IT WAS JUST ENDING.
BUT THEN
THE SECOND MOVIE STARTED.
HELLO, DESIGN TEAM.
WHAT?!
WHOA!
NO.
AND IT WAS
THE TY PENNINGTON MOVIE.
NOT MY FAVORITE MOVIE.
NO.
Ed: THAT WAS RATED "R,"
THAT WAS.
TO FIND OUT MORE
ABOUT THE PRODUCTS USED
ON TONIGHT'S SHOW,
GO TO abc.com.
I CAN'T BREATHE,
SO I CAN'T SLEEP.
AND THE NEXT DAY I PAY FOR IT.
I TRIED DECONGESTANTS...
I TOSSED AND TURNED...
I EVEN VAPORIZED.
AND THEN I FOUGHT BACK
WITH DRUG-FREE BREATHE RIGHT.
THESE NASAL STRIPS
INSTANTLY OPEN MY NOSE,
LIKE A BREATH OF FRESH AIR.
I WAS BREATHING
AND SLEEPING BETTER.
[ Female Announcer ] EXERCISE
YOUR RIGHT TO BREATHE RIGHT.
GET TWO FREE STRIPS
AT BREATHERIGHT.COM.
HEY IT'S YOUR RIGHT
TO BREATHE RIGHT.
♪
[ Female Announcer ] MAY YOUR
HOLIDAYS BE MERRY AND BRIGHT.
MERRY PRINGLES.
PROGRESSIVE DIRECT AND OTHER
CAR INSURANCE COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
CALL OR CLICK TODAY.
NESPRESSO.
WHERE I NEVER HAVE TO COMPROMISE
ON ANYTHING.
♪
WHERE JUST ONE TOUCH
CREATES THE PERFECT COFFEE.
WHERE EVERY CAPPUCCINO AND LATTE
IS ONLY MADE WITH FRESH MILK.
AND WHERE THE STAFF
IS EXCEPTIONALLY FRIENDLY.
♪
NESPRESSO. WHAT ELSE?
Paige:
WE GOT AN INVITATION FROM TY
TO GO TO
A DRIVE-IN MOVIE THEATER.
I MEAN, HOW COOL IS THAT.
WE'RE ALL EXCITED.
WE'RE SITTING
IN THIS CONVERTIBLE,
WE'RE WAITING
FOR THE MOVIE TO START.
ALL OF A SUDDEN...
HELLO, DESIGN TEAM.
NOT MY FAVORITE MOVIE.
NO.
I GUESS YOU'RE WONDERING
WHY YOU'RE
AT A DRIVE-IN MOVIE THEATER.
YEP.
TO WATCH A MOVIE, YEAH?
WELL, I'VE GOT
A BIT OF A CHALLENGE
FOR THIS WEEK,
AND HERE'S THE THING.
THE FRIDAY FAMILY REALLY LOVES
SPENDING TIME TOGETHER
AND WATCHING MOVIES,
BUT THEY'VE NEVER HAD THE SPACE
TO REALLY BE ABLE TO ENJOY
THAT OUTDOOR-MOVIE EXPERIENCE.
WELL, THIS WEEK,
YOU'RE GONNA CHANGE ALL THAT.
SO LOOK AROUND, SOAK IT ALL IN,
BECAUSE I WANT YOU GUYS
TO DESIGN
A DRIVE-IN MOVIE THEATER
FOR THE FRIDAYS' BACKYARD.
WOW.
I CAN'T WAIT TO SEE
WHAT YOU COME UP WITH.
SO ENJOY, 'CAUSE
I'M GONNA ENJOY THE MOVIE.
WOW.
Jillian:
SO, HE WANTS US TO DO --
HE WANTS US
TO REPLICATE THIS
IN THE FRIDAYS' BACKYARD?
YES.
Michael:
SO, WE CAN GET A BIG SCREEN
AND PUT TWO OR THREE, FOUR CARS
RIGHT IN FRONT OF IT,
GET THESE SPEAKERS.
THIS IS GONNA BE THE COOLEST
BACKYARD IN HISTORY.
BREAK!
TY!
I JUST WANT TO SAY, MAN,
THANKS FOR MAKING THIS HAPPEN.
I JUST -- I KNOW
SAVING THESE BRICKS --
WE SAVED A LOT
OF MATERIALS, RIGHT?
WE SAVED A LOT OF MATERIALS
FROM THE HOME.
I REALLY WANT TO DO SOMETHING
VERY MEANINGFUL FOR THE FAMILY,
AND I THINK EACH OF THESE BRICKS
CAN SORT OF REPRESENT
THE KIDS
THAT THEY'VE FOSTERED.
ONCE THESE ARE ALL
STACKED UP IN THEIR ROOM,
IT'S REALLY
GONNA LET THEM SEE
JUST HOW MUCH INCREDIBLE STUFF
THEY'VE DONE FOR THESE KIDS.
Waltrip: HEY, MICHAEL.
HOW ARE YOU, MICHAEL?
NICE TO SEE YOU.
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
HOW'S IT GOING?
I'M DOING GREAT.
THIS IS AWESOME.
Michael:
SO, TY GAVE US OUR CHALLENGE.
WE'RE GONNA CREATE
A DRIVE-IN MOVIE THEATER
IN THE FAMILY'S BACKYARD.
NOW, THE FIRST THING WE'RE GONNA
NEED IS CARS FOR SEATING.
AND IN CHARLOTTE,
MICHAEL WALTRIP
HAS HIS FACTORY
WHERE HE MAKES RACECARS.
THIS GUY HAS WON
TWO DAYTONA 500s.
I MEAN, IT'S AS GOOD AS IT GETS.
AND IT'S HUGE, AND IT'S JUST
FULL OF MACHINERY AND CARS.
IT'S PRETTY COOL.
THEY MAKE EVERYTHING ON SITE.
SO, HERE'S THE THING --
THIS ISN'T GONNA WORK.
WHAT? THIS WOULD BE A GREAT WAY
TO WATCH A MOVIE.
IT -- IT'S REALLY
NOT VERY COMFORTABLE.
Paige: FOR THE SEATING
FOR THIS DRIVE-IN THEATER,
WE WANT TO DO
A COUPLE OF CARS AND A TRUCK,
MAYBE THROW SOME PILLOWS
BACK THERE, YOU KNOW,
A NICE, BIG TRUCK-BED LINER,
AND ALL OF A SUDDEN,
YOU'VE GOT SEATING FOR 15.
NICE.
Ed: WE'RE GONNA PUT CARS
IN THE BACKYARD.
HOWEVER, THE CARS WE'VE GOT NEED
SOME SERIOUS WORK DONE ON THEM,
BECAUSE WE DON'T WANT
ENGINES IN THEM
AND OIL LEAKING ON THE GRASS.
SO PAIGE IS GONNA
TAKE CARE OF HER TRUCK,
MICHAEL'S GONNA
TAKE CARE OF HIS CAR,
WITH THE HELP
OF MICHAEL WALTRIP,
I'M GONNA TAKE CARE OF MY CAR,
WHICH IS GONNA BE pink.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
YOU HEARD ME. OKAY, FINE.
IT'S GOING TO BE PINK.
[ PNEUMATIC WRENCH WHIRS ]
Jillian: THANK YOU GUYS
SO MUCH FOR COMING.
AND YOU'LL ALL
FROM CROSSNORE ACADEMY, RIGHT?
WE HAD SOME KIDS
FROM CROSSNORE ACADEMY.
IT'S ESSENTIALLY A SCHOOL,
BUT IT ALSO ACTS AS
A BIT OF A GROUP HOME
FOR CHILDREN
THAT ARE WAITING FOR ADOPTION
OR COMING FROM
A TROUBLED FAMILY.
JAMES AND DEVONDA
ADOPTED FIVE SIBLINGS
FROM THE CROSSNORE ACADEMY
TO KEEP THEM TOGETHER.
I'VE BEEN AT THREE FOSTER HOMES
BEFORE CROSSNORE.
OKAY.
SO I'VE BEEN IN THE SYSTEM
FOR ABOUT SIX YEARS.
CROSSNORE HAS REALLY HELPED ME
A LOT, YOU KNOW, WITH LIFE.
AND I THINK IT'LL ALWAYS
BE THERE FOR ME.
WHAT MADE YOU DECIDE
TO COME HERE TODAY?
THEY GAVE A HOME TO FIVE KIDS
THAT REALLY NEEDED IT,
AND IT'S JUST REALLY NICE
TO GIVE SOMETHING BACK
TO SOMEBODY
THAT'S HELPED SO MANY PEOPLE.
YEAH.
I'M REALLY LEARNING
ABOUT WHAT THEY'VE BEEN THROUGH.
I REALIZE WE HAVE AN OPPORTUNITY
TO MAKE THESE KIDS' CHRISTMAS
A LITTLE BIT BETTER.
[ TRUCK BEEPING ]
OKAY, SO,
I'VE GOT MORE FAMILY PHOTOS.
AND WHAT WE'RE WORKING ON, YOU
GUYS, IS THE FAMILY TIMELINE.
IT'S GONNA BE
THE CHRONOLOGY OF THE FAMILY,
STARTING FROM
THE VERY BEGINNING.
OH, YEAH.
IT'S A WEDDING PHOTO, RIGHT?
SO THAT WOULD BE,
LIKE, HERE.
BIG MOMENT, LITTLE MOMENT,
AND THEN FIVE SIBLINGS.
HAVE THEM IN THERE WITH
SPECIAL MOMENTS AND BIRTHDAYS.
I THINK THIS IS SOMETHING THAT
EVERYONE IN THE WHOLE FAMILY
IS REALLY GONNA APPRECIATE.
WE WENT TO JAMAICA, MONTEGO BAY,
FOR OUR VACATION.
IT WAS, LIKE, SO COOL BECAUSE ME
AND MY FAMILY COULD BE TOGETHER.
IT WAS JUST SO FUN.
IT'S JUST SOMETHING
THAT WE'VE NEVER EXPERIENCED,
AND WE'RE NEVER
GONNA FORGET THIS.
[ CELLPHONE RINGING ]
HELLO?
HELLO, FRIDAY FAMILY!
HEY, TY.
TY!
HI!
TODAY YOU GUYS
ARE GETTING A REAL TREAT,
BECAUSE YOU'RE GONNA
GET TO HANG OUT
with the Jamaican National
Bobsled team trainer
RICKY McINTOSH.
[ GASPS ]
WHAT DID HE SAY?
HE'S GONNA SHOW YOU
EVERYTHING YOU NEED TO KNOW
about bobsledding and...
TAKE YOU ON A REAL
BOBSLED RIDE.
AAH!
YEAH!
Girl:
THIS IS SO FUN.
Girl #2:
THIS IS LIKE A MOUNTAIN.
IT IS A MOUNTAIN.
THIS IS A TOP-OF-THE-HILL
MOUNTAIN.
RIGHT. HEY.
HEY, HOW ARE YOU?
HEY, I'M RICKY.
JAMES.
HEY, HOW ARE YOU DOING?
VERY NICE TO MEET YOU.
THIS IS
MY FRIDAY FAMILY.
ALL RIGHT.
I'M RICKY McINTOSH.
I'VE BEEN A MEMBER OF JAMAICA
BOBSLED TEAM SINCE 1990.
WE GOT TO SIMULATE A BOBSLED.
THE CHILDREN LOVED IT.
HOW DO I STEER?
IF THE CAR IS GOING
TO THE RIGHT,
JUST MOVE THE BODY
TO THE RIGHT.
IF IT'S GOING TO THE LEFT,
JUST MOVE TO IT.
JUST LET IT TAKE YOU.
FIRST, IT'S GOING REALLY SLOW,
BUT AFTER YOU TURN THE CORNER,
IT JUST STARTS GOING
REALLY FAST.
THEN, YOU GO DOWN THIS BIG OLD
HILL, AND I'M, LIKE, SCREAMING.
IT WAS FUN.
WHOO-HOO-HOO!
AND ST. JUDE CHILDREN'S
RESEARCH HOSPITAL CREATED
A SPECIAL BRAIN TUMOR
TREATMENT JUST FOR ARIANNA.
OUR BOLD, NEW PROCEDURE IS
HELPING TO EXTEND HER LIFE...
AND GIVE HER FAMILY HOPE.
LOOK WHAT I MADE.
BEAUTIFUL...
HUG YOUR CHILD TONIGHT...
GIVE THANKS FOR THE HEALTHY
KIDS IN YOUR LIFE.
AND GIVE TO THOSE WHO ARE
NOT. GO TO ST. JUDE DOT ORG
OR SHOP WHERE EVER YOU SEE
THE ST. JUDE LOGO.
WHY LET CONSTIPATION
STRY MIRALAX.?
MIRLAX WORKS
DIFFERENTLY THAN
OTHER LAXATIVES.
IT DRAWS WATER INTO YOUR COLON
TO UNBLOCK YOUR
SYSTEM NATURALLY.
DON'T WAIT TO FEEL GREAT.
MIRALAX.
GINGERBREAD COOKIE COFFEES --
NO WONDER PEOPLE GET JOLLY
AROUND THE HOLIDAYS.
TRY DUNKIN' DONUTS'
HOLIDAY FLAVORS.
PICK SOME UP WHERE YOU BUY
GROCERIES, BEFORE THEY'RE GONE.
AMERICA RUNS ON DUNKIN'.
HOW MUCH IS
YOUR CURRENT PHONE BILL?
FOUR SIXTEEN SEVENTY SIX
A MONTH!
OKAY, COME WITH ME --
WE'RE GONNA SAVE YOU MONEY.
WITH STRAIGHT TALK
AT WALMART,
YOU GET UNLIMITED TALK,
TEXT AND DATA
FOR ONLY $45 A MONTH
PER PHONE.
WOULD WE GET
THE SAME COVERAGE?
SAME COVERAGE
ON AMERICA'S BEST NETWORKS.
YOU SAVED $146.76
BY SWITCHING TO STRAIGHT TALK.
AWESOME!
NOW YOU CAN AFFORD
TO SHARE YOUR ALLOWANCE
WITH ME.
GET THE SEASON'S
HOTTEST SMARTPHONES
LIKE THE SAMSUNG GALAXY S2
AND GET STRAIGHT TALK
WITH UNLIMITED DATA
FOR JUST $45 A MONTH --
FROM AMERICA'S
GIFT HEADQUARTERS. WALMART.
♪
Ed: HELLO, JAY!
THAT'S WHAT I LIKE TO SEE --
OUR BUILDERS HANGING DRYWALL.
GOODY.
YES, SIR.
OKAY, NOW, LISTEN,
THIS IS CHRIS' ROOM.
YES.
NOW, HE LOVES BASKETBALL.
YES, HE DOES.
I PLAYED WITH HIM
BEFORE HE WENT ON HOLIDAY,
AND HE THRASHED
THE PANTS OFF OF ME.
SO ALTHOUGH
THIS IS GONNA BE
LIKE A VIP BOX
IN A BASKETBALL STADIUM,
I'M THINKING,
WHY DON'T WE PUT TWO BASKETS,
AND HE CAN PLAY
WITH HIS FRIENDS.
IN FACT,
IF YOU STEP ASIDE A SECOND,
I'LL HAVE A LITTLE WARM--
HEY, HEY, WE'RE NOT DONE.
JUST A COUPLE OF --
NO, NO, NO, HANG ON.
NO WAY.
LET ME JUST AT LEAST
HIT THE WALL, SO I'LL
KNOW THE DISTANCE.
JAY, LET ME JUST
HIT THE WALL, JAY.
LOOK, I MAY NOT BE
GOOD AT BASKETBALL,
BUT YOU KNOW
WHAT I AM GOOD AT?
WHAT'S THAT?
SOCCER!
GOAL! WHOO-HOO!
[ GROANS ]
[ SIGHS ]
[ WHIRRING ]
WHAT?
THIS IS AMAZING!
OKAY, SO, LET'S DO A FEW PURPLE
BOOKS AND MAYBE A BROWN BOOK.
SO, THIS IS ACTUALLY
FOR KAMAYA'S ROOM,
AND SHE IS SUPER INTO
READING AND WRITING,
AND SO WE'RE GONNA KIND OF
DESIGN THE WHOLE ROOM
AROUND BOOKS.
SO, I'M THINKING, OKAY,
WE'RE GONNA HAVE
BOOKS HIGH, BOOKS LOW,
BASICALLY FLOOR TO CEILING.
YOU CAN PUT A CLOSET
ON ONE END.
RIGHT.
A LITTLE WRITING AREA.
OKAY.
SO, IT'LL BE, LIKE,
THIS PIECE WOULD BE, LIKE...
HI.
AWESOME.
SHE'S TOTALLY
GOT IT DOWN PAT HERE.
STOW IT.
BUT WE CAN MAKE THIS WORK,
RIGHT?
RIGHT.
YEAH, MAYBE WE CAN MAKE IT
SO WE CAN JUST
TAKE IT AND SLIDE IT OUT
AND EXPOSE A SPACE UNDER THE BED
WHERE SHE COULD REALLY
HIDE AWAY FROM EVERYONE.
YEAH. ARE YOU OKAY IN THERE?
YOU'RE JUST READING AWAY.
READING AWAY.
DOING GREAT.
WE SHOULD BRING THAT LIGHT
OVER FOR HER --
I MEAN, SO SHE COULD READ.
WOULD THAT BE NICE?
PERFECT.
YEAH?
SO, ONE OF THE PROJECTS
I'M WORKING ON
FOR DEVONDA AND JAMES'
MASTER BEDROOM
IS I REALLY WANT TO GIVE THEM
SOMETHING
THAT SYMBOLIZES
THEIR FAMILY COMING TOGETHER.
IF YOU THINK ABOUT IT,
THE FIVE SIBLINGS --
THEY'VE JUST NOW BECOME
PART OF THE FAMILY,
SO THEY'RE FINALLY
FRIDAYS.
AND I THINK,
SINCE A QUILT IS WARMTH,
IT'S A SYMBOL
OF SORT OF FAMILY,
SO I'D LOVE IT IF YOU GUYS
COULD HELP ME PUT TOGETHER
SOME OF THE DIFFERENT
FABRICS.
I'M THINKING MAYBE SOME BLUES,
MAYBE SOME BROWNS
AND THEN A NICE, SOLID
SORT OF NEUTRAL
THAT WE COULD EMBROIDER
THE NAMES ON.
SO, THE IDEA IS,
ONCE IT'S ALL STITCHED TOGETHER,
THE QUILT ITSELF WILL SYMBOLIZE
THAT THEY'RE ONE BIG FAMILY.
SOUND GOOD?
SOUNDS GREAT.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S DO IT.
MELISSA.
MICHAEL,
SO NICE TO MEET YOU.
HOW ARE YOU? YOU TOO.
THIS PLACE IS AMAZING.
WELL, WELCOME
TO THE WHITEWATER CENTER.
GLAD TO HAVE YOU GUYS.
THANK YOU, THANK YOU.
I'M REALLY EXCITED.
GOT TO TELL YOU,
THE FRIDAY FAMILY ARE AMAZING.
AND I WAS OUT PLAYING WITH THEM
IN THE BACKYARD,
AND THEY LOVE ACTIVITIES,
THEY LOVE CLIMBING,
THEY LOVE SPORTS,
THEY LOVE BEING TOGETHER,
SO WHAT I WANT TO DO IS PUT SOME
OF THAT ACTUALLY IN THE HOUSE.
THAT'S AWESOME.
SO I'M HERE TO GET
A LITTLE INSPIRATION.
WELL, YOU'RE
AT THE RIGHT PLACE.
WE'VE GOT A LITTLE BIT
OF ALL OF THAT HERE.
COOL.
WHAT IS THAT?
THAT WOULD BE
OUR CLIMBING WALL.
WOW.
DO YOU THINK I CAN DO THAT?
I'M PRETTY SURE
YOU CAN TACKLE IT.
AWESOME.
I'M WORKING ON A PLACE TO LET
THESE KIDS BLOW SOME STEAM OFF.
YOU KNOW, SUMMERS HERE
ARE PRETTY MUGGY AND HOT,
AND THE WINTERS
ARE REALLY, REALLY COLD,
SO THEY NEED
A PLACE INDOORS TO PLAY.
ALL RIGHT,
YOU READY FOR THIS?
OKAY.
JUST GO AHEAD AND START CLIMBING
WHEN YOU'RE READY.
OKAY, I'M GOOD.
ALL RIGHT.
WELL [SIGHS]
THAT WAS NOTHING.
ONE OF THE COOL THINGS
THAT I DID
WAS CLIMB THIS GIANT CARGO NET.
SO I'M THINKING, IF I CAN GET
ONE OF THESE CARGO NETS
AND ACTUALLY PUT IT IN THE
HOUSE, IT'D BE OVER A PLAY AREA.
CARGO NET, WE COULD PUT IN.
I KNOW JUST THE SPOT.
MAYBE I'VE GOT
SOMETHING HERE.
THERE'S NO WAY YOU CAN PUT
ONE OF THESE IN THE HOUSE,
BUT YOU CAN'T LEAVE
THE WHITEWATER CENTER
WITHOUT DOING THIS.
OKAY.
YOU READY TO ZIP?
I'M READY!
LET'S DO IT.
OH, MY GOD.
WHOA! WAIT. OH!
[ LAUGHS ]
WHOA-OA!
♪
THANK YOU.
FOR WHAT?
WHEN THINGS WERE TOUGH,
YOU KEPT BELIEVING IN ME...
YOU HELPED
MAKE THIS HAPPEN.
THANK YOU.
[ Jane ] BEHIND EVERY OPEN HEART
IS A STORY.
TELL YOURS WITH MY OPEN HEART
COLLECTION AT KAY JEWELERS,
THE NUMBER ONE JEWELRY STORE
IN AMERICA.
THERE ARE MILLIONS OF REASONS
TO GIVE ONE,
BUT THE MESSAGE
IS ALWAYS THE SAME.
KEEP YOUR HEART OPEN...
AND LOVE WILL ALWAYS
FIND ITS WAY IN.
YOU DID IT, DADDY.
WE DID IT.
♪ EVERY KISS BEGINS WITH KAY
OH, IT'S GREAT!
NOW I CAN BREW MY COFFEE
JUST THE WAY I LOVE IT.
HOW DO YOU DO THAT?
WELL, INSIDE THE BREWER,
THERE'S THIS TRAIN
THAT'S POWERFUL ENOUGH
TO CARRY MORE COFFEE
AND FRESH WATER TO MAKE COFFEE
THAT'S STRONGER
AND BIGGER...
AND EVEN HOTTER!
ACTUALLY, I JUST PRESS
THIS BUTTON.
BREW THE COFFEE YOU LOVE --
STRONGER, BIGGER, OR HOTTER --
WITH THE KEURIG VUE.
Introducing NOOK HD -
the world's best 7" tablet made
for reading and entertainment.
Your favorite magazines and
catalogs look better than ever.
And with scrapbooking,
you can save the
things you love,
bring them all together,
And be inspired like
never before.
Scrapbooking. Create
yours with Nook HD -
and even bigger with HD+.
Find yours at Barnes & Noble.
LET'FOR AN IDEA.S -
A GRAND IDEA CALLED AMERICA.
THE IDEA THAT
IF YOU WORK HARD,
IF YOU HAVE A DREAM,
IF YOU WORK WITH
YOUR NEIGHBORS...
YOU CAN DO MOST ANYTHING.
THIS LED TO OTHER IDEAS
LIKE LIBERTY
AND ROCK 'N' ROLL.
TO FREE MARKETS,
FREE ENTERPRISE,
AND FREE REFILLS.
IT PUT A MAN ON THE MOON
AND A PHONE IN YOUR POCKET.
OUR COUNTRY'S GONE THROUGH A LOT
OVER THE CENTURIES AND A HALF.
BUT THIS IDEA ISN'T FRAGILE.
WHEN TIMES GET TOUGH,
IT RALLIES US AS ONE.
EVERY DAY, MORE PEOPLE
BELIEVE IN THE AMERICAN IDEA
AND WHEN THEY DO,
THE DREAM COMES TRUE.
WE'RE GRATEFUL
TO BE A PART OF IT.
♪
MICHAEL!
DO YOU WANT TO GO GET
SOME LUNCH?
THAT WALL -- I'M THINKING ABOUT
DOING GRAY WITH A --
CHICKEN SALAD
WOULD BE GOOD.
SANDWICH, PERHAPS?
HEY, DOES THIS THING
OPEN UP?
SURE.
OH, THAT MAKES IT
A LOT EASIER.
DID YOU GET MY --
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
YEAH, YOU'RE TALKING
ABOUT THE PAINT.
LUNCH.
LUNCH?
WELL --
I'M TALKING ABOUT
THE PAINT ON THAT WALL.
THAT'S SOUNDPROOF?
YES, IT'S COMPLETELY
SOUNDPROOF.
AH, FOR MOM AND DAD.
FAMILY ROOM, PLAYROOM.
THEY WON'T HAVE TO HEAR
THE KIDS.
NICE CALL. GOOD CALL.
BUT THEY CAN SEE THEM.
MOM AND DAD
ARE GONNA LOVE THAT.
Ty:
SO, IF YOU GUYS WILL HELP ME,
WE'LL JUST GO IN
AND JUST PAINT RIGHT INSIDE.
THAT LOOKS GOOD.
YEAH, I THINK THIS IS GONNA MEAN
SO MUCH TO THE FAMILY.
IMAGINE WHEN THEY WALK IN,
THEY SEE ALL THE NAMES
OF ALL THE DIFFERENT KIDS
THEY'VE FOSTERED.
IT'S GONNA BE PRETTY COOL.
WE'VE GOT A LOT OF BRICKS.
A LOT OF NAMES.
GET BUSY.
Ed:
HOW ARE WE DOING, GANG?
OH, HEY, GUYS!
HEY!
WOW!
LOOK AT YOU LOVELY,
EAGER BODIES.
LOOK AT YOU.
WE'VE GOT MORE STUFF.
Jillian: CROSSNORE SCHOOL
ACTS AS A BIT OF A GROUP HOME
FOR CHILDREN
THAT ARE WAITING FOR ADOPTION
OR ARE COMING FROM
A TROUBLED FAMILY.
THE CHILDREN WHO ARE THERE
ACTUALLY COME
WITH NO BELONGINGS.
THEY HAVE NEVER HAD SOMETHING
THAT WAS MADE
SPECIFICALLY FOR THEM.
WHAT YOU GUYS ARE DOING
IS EFFECTIVELY
GIVING THEM THEIR OWN
PERSONALIZED THINGS.
AND WHEN I SAY "PERSONALIZED,"
I ACTUALLY MEAN PERSONALIZED.
Ed: THE MAJORITY OF THE PRESENTS
WERE DONATED
BY KIDS ACROSS AMERICA,
DONATING SOME OF THEIR ALLOWANCE
OR ALL OF IT.
NOT ALL OF THEM,
BUT A FAIR CHUNK OF THEM,
HAVE ACTUALLY COME FROM A PLACE
CALLED ALLOWANCE MANAGER,
WHERE KIDS ACTUALLY GIVE
A PORTION
OF THEIR WEEKLY ALLOWANCE FROM
THEIR PARENTS TO THIS PLACE,
AND THIS IS THE MONEY --
THIS IS THE STUFF
THAT'S BEEN BOUGHT WITH THEM.
THESE GUYS SHOULD COME WITH US
TO DELIVER THE PRESENTS.
WHO WANTS TO COME
TO CROSSNORE?
All: YEAH!
Jillian: HI, GUYS.
All: HI!
HOW ARE YOU?
All: GOOD!
I HAVE A SURPRISE
FOR YOU GUYS.
BUT BEFORE I TELL YOU
WHAT THE SURPRISE IS,
I THINK THE FRIDAYS,
ESPECIALLY THOSE FAB FIVE,
WOULD PROBABLY WANT TO KNOW
THAT WE'RE HERE, RIGHT?
YEAH?
All: YEAH!
OKAY.
HI, FRIDAYS.
Fridays: HI, JILLIAN!
I'M HERE RIGHT NOW,
SOMEWHERE I THINK
YOU GUYS ARE GONNA RECOGNIZE.
I'M AT THE CROSSNORE SCHOOL,
AND THIS
IS WHERE FIVE OF YOU CAME
BEFORE YOU WERE ADOPTED
BY THE FRIDAYS.
AND THERE'S A FEW
THAT'D LIKE TO SAY HI.
All: HI!
Fridays: HI!
A LOT OF THESE KIDS KNOW WHAT
YOU GUYS HAVE BEEN THROUGH,
AND FOR THEM,
I THINK YOU REPRESENT HOPE
THAT THERE IS
A HAPPY ENDING FOR THEM.
AND I THINK THERE'S A FEW
THAT WANT TO SAY A FEW THINGS.
HI, FRIDAY FAMILY.
IT'S LINDSAY.
All: HEY!
I THINK IT'S JUST
AN AMAZING THING
THAT YOU WOULD ADOPT
FIVE KIDS LIKE THAT.
I'M REALLY HAPPY THAT YOU GUYS
NOW HAVE A FAMILY OF YOUR OWN.
AND BLESSINGS FROM ME TO YOU,
AND HAVE A MERRY CHRISTMAS.
HI, FRIDAY FAMILY.
I HOPE YOU'RE HAVING FUN.
All: THANK YOU!
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
AS YOU KNOW,
THERE ARE SOME KIDS HERE
WHO WON'T BE SPENDING CHRISTMAS
WITH THEIR FAMILY THIS YEAR,
AND SO WE'VE DECIDED THAT WE'RE
GONNA BRING CHRISTMAS TO THEM.
SAY HI TO ED SANDERS
AND MR. CLAUS!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
AH, THIS IS IT.
[ CHUCKLES ]
MOMENTUM!
DON'T LET ME STOP!
PRESENTS FOR EVERYONE!
MERRY CHRISTMAS!
THAT IS AWESOME!
EVERY CHILD
AT CROSSNORE TODAY
IS RECEIVING
PERSONALIZED GIFT BAGS
FULL OF CHRISTMAS GOODIES
AND ALL OF THE ESSENTIALS
THAT THEY NEED.
ALL RIGHT!
OH, WOW.
DO WE HAVE AN ASHLEY?
ASHLEY?
James: CHILDREN WHO'VE BEEN
IN GROUP HOMES OR FOSTER HOMES,
WHO'VE RECEIVED, YOU KNOW,
USUALLY USED CLOTHES,
USED GOODS, USED TOYS,
BUT TO RECEIVE
SOMETHING OF THEIR OWN
AND TO HAVE THEIR NAME ON IT,
IT MEANS A LOT TO THEM.
I'M HAVING THE BEST CHRISTMAS
OF MY LIFE, GUYS!
ALL RIGHT!
WE'RE HAVING A GREAT TIME
HERE AT CROSSNORE,
BUT IT'S GONNA CONTINUE
ACROSS THE JAMAICAN SOIL,
BECAUSE TODAY YOU GUYS
ARE GONNA GO TO A LOCAL SCHOOL
AND GIVE OUT PRESENTS
TO ALL THE KIDS THERE.
ALL RIGHT!
YOU'RE GONNA CELEBRATE
CHRISTMAS JAMAICAN STYLE!
THANK YOU!
THANK YOU, THANK YOU, THANK YOU!
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
Boy: THIS IS GONNA BE FUN.
James:
CHRISTMAS HAS ALWAYS BEEN
A GREAT HOLIDAY
FOR THE FRIDAY FAMILY.
WE WANT TO SHOW OUR CHILDREN
TO GIVE UNSELFISHLY, YOU KNOW,
TO OTHERS, YOU KNOW,
IF THERE'S A NEED.
SO THIS WHOLE EXPERIENCE
IS JUST AMAZING.
YOU HAVE A MERRY CHRISTMAS,
OKAY?
SANTA CLAUS AND MISS DEVONDA
GAVE IT TO YOU, OKAY?
[ SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY ]
Devonda: PEOPLE DON'T REALIZE
THE SIMPLE THINGS IN LIFE
THAT WE TAKE FOR GRANTED --
THAT'S ALL THE CHILDREN WANT.
SO IT'S VERY MUCH IMPORTANT
THAT PEOPLE REACH OUT AND
GIVE BACK TO A CHILD IN NEED.
ALL RIGHT!
[ CHUCKLES ]
TO GO TO THAT SCHOOL
AND GIVE THOSE CHILDREN GIFTS,
TO SEE THOSE CHILDREN'S FACES
LIGHT UP,
OH, MY GOODNESS,
THEY ABSOLUTELY LOVED IT.
THE HUGS AND THE KISSES
THAT WE GOT --
THAT JUST -- OH,
THAT JUST PUT ICING ON THE CAKE.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
♪
Michael:
HEY, MAN. WHAT'S GOING ON?
WHAT'S WRONG?
I DON'T KNOW. IT JUST FEELS LIKE
IT'S OVER, YOU KNOW?
OVER?
YEAH.
HEY, IT'S NOT OVER.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
IT'S NOT OVER?
IT'S A TWO-HOUR.
WE'VE GOT ANOTHER HOUR?!
YES, THERE'S MORE!
IT'S NOT OVER?!
IT'S NOT OVER!
MERRY CHRISTMAS, MICHAEL!
MERRY CHRISTMAS!
IT'S NOT OVER!
IT'S NOT OVER.
MERRY CHRISTMAS,
GUY WITH A 2x4!
MERRY CHRISTMAS!
IT'S NOT OVER,
CARDBOARD BOX!
[ LAUGHS ]
MERRY CHRISTMAS!
All:
DON'T GO ANYWHERE, BECAUSE
EVERY TIME THE BUS MOVES,
AN ANGEL GETS HIS WINGS!
[ CROWD CHEERING ]
GOOD MORNING, FRIDAY FAMILY!
[ ALL CHEERING ]
THEY'VE FOSTERED OVER 30 KIDS.
NOW THEY'VE ALSO ADOPTED
FIVE SIBLINGS.
Ty: IF YOU HADN'T TAKEN IN
THESE FIVE SIBLINGS,
WHAT WOULD HAVE HAPPENED
TO THEM?
THE OLDER TWO
WOULD HAVE BEEN SPLIT UP.
THEY'VE GIVEN THOSE KIDS
A CHANCE
AT HOPE, AT A NEW BEGINNING,
AND BOY, IS THIS GONNA BE
A SPECIAL CHRISTMAS.
HELLO, DESIGN TEAM.
I WANT YOU GUYS TO DESIGN
A DRIVE-IN MOVIE THEATER
FOR THE FRIDAYS' BACK YARD.
WOW.
Paige: SOMEONE'S BEEN
SNEAKING AROUND HELPING ME.
HIS HEART HAS DEFINITELY GROWN
THREE SIZES.
COMING UP NEXT...
CHECK THIS OUT!
[ ALL SCREAMING ]
SPECIAL DELIVERY FROM
TWO-TIME DAYTONA 500 CHAMPION