AND HOW THEY DIED.
WE ALSO SEE HOW RESILIENT PEOPLE
IN THE COMMUNITY ARE AS THEY
FACE THE HOLIDAYS IN THE SHADOW
OF THIS MASSACRE.
GOOD EVENING, AND THANK YOU FOR
JOINING US.
THE SHOOTING KILLED 12 GIRLS AND
EIGHT BOYS, ALL BETWEEN THE AGES
OF SIX AND SEVEN.
WE'RE LIVE IN CONNECTICUT WITH
THE LATEST.
REPORTER: GOOD EVENING FROM A
COMMUNITY STILL EL REELING FROM
THE SHOOTINGS AND NOW BEING
FORCED TO DEAL WITH GRIM NEW
DETAILS COMING OUT AS THE
MEDICAL EXAMINER SAYS TONIGHT
THAT SOME OF THE CHILDREN WHO
DIED IN THE SHOOTING WERE SHOT
AS MANY AS 11 TIMES.
>> ANGUISHED RESIDENTS OF
NEWTOWN STRUGGLE TO COPE WITH
THE LOSS OF SO MANY TO EVIL.
CONNECTICUT'S GOVERNOR PAID
TRIBUTE TO THE VICTIMS.
>> THOSE EDUCATORS AND THOSE
INNOCENT LITTLE BOYS AND GIRLS,
WERE TAKEN FROM THEIR FAMILIES
FAR TOO SOON.
>> BUT IT SEEMED ALMOST NOWHERE
ARE EMOTIONS RUNNING STRONGER
THAN RIGHT HERE AS A MAKESHIFT
MEMORIAL THAT SPRUNG 5U7 HUNDRED
YARD FROM THE SCHOOL, WHERE
PEOPLE ARE COMING HERE TO LIGHT
CANDLES AND TO REMEMBER.
REPORTER: ALL DAY LONG PEOPLE
CAKE CARRYING FLOWERS AND
HONORING THE 20 CHILDREN AND SIX
ADULTS WHO DIED.
STILL UNDER INTENSE
INVESTIGATION.
THE DETECTIVES WILL ANALYZE
EVERYTHING AND PUT A COMPLETE
PICTURE TOGETHER.
REPORTER: OFFICIALS SAY THEY
RECOVERED VERY GOOD EVIDENCE
THAT MAY PROVIDE ANSWERS ABOUT
WHAT TRIGGERED THE HORRIFYING
CHAIN OF EVENT, WHEN
20-YEAR-OLD al-ADAM LANZA SHOT
TO DEATH HIS MOTHER NANCY IN
THEIR HOME AND THEN HEADED TO
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, WEARING A
BULLETPROOF VEST AND ARMED WITH
WEAPONS, HIGH-UNDER POWERED
PISTOLS AND A SEMI AUTOMATIC
RIFLE.
>> I THOUGHT WE WOULD ALL DIE.
>> THE MEDICAL EXAMINER
COMPLETED THE GRIM TASK OF
IDENTIFYING OFF THE VICTIMS,
INCLUDING 27-YEAR-OLD HERO
TISCHER, VICTORIA SOTO, WHO
THREW HERSELF IN FRONT OF THE
GUNMAN TO SHIELD HER STUDENTS,
AND THE PRINCIPAL, DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG, WHO DRIED TO STOP
THE RAMPAGE AND PAID WITH HER
LIFE.
ONE CHILD IS REMEMBERED BY HER
FATHER.
>> WE WANT EVERYBODY TO -- THIS
INCLUDES THE FAMILY OF THE
SHOOTER.
REPORTER: AND WE YOU KNOW THAT
ALL OF THE CHILDREN WHO DIED
WERE JUST SIX YEARS OLD AND
SEVEN YEARS OLD, ONLY IN FIRST
GRADE, AND NOW THEY WON'T GATE
CHANCE TO GROW UP.
LIVE IN NEWTOWN, ABC-7.
BACK TO YOU.
>> Ama: IT'S HARD TO HEAR THE
EXTERIORS COMING OUT, THE
PARENTS AND HOW THEY MUST BE
FEELING.
HAVE WE HEARD FROM OTHER
FAMILIES OF THE TRAGEDY?
REPORTER: YES.
THEY'RE BEGINNING TO COME OUT
AND GIVE STATEMENTS.
ONE FAMILY OF THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST SAID THE SCHOOL
COALITION WAS DOING GOD'S
WORKED.
SHE REALLY BELIEVED THAT, AND
NOW, OF COURSE, SHE'S GONE.
>> Ama: THANK YOU FOR THE
UPDATE.
WE APPRECIATE ALL YOU HAVE BEEN
DOING IN CONNECTICUT.
>> WE'RE GETTING MORE
INFORMATION TODAY ABOUT THE
GUNMAN WHO EMPLOYS IDENTIFIED AS
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA.
THIS AS A PICTURE OF HIM FROM
2005.
DESCRIBED AS SOME BY BRILLIANT
BUT REMOTE.
A LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIAL WHO
WAS BRIEFED ON THE INVESTIGATION
SAYS LANZA IS BELIEVED TO HAVE
SUFFERED FROM A PERSONALITY
DISORDER.
HIS PARENTS FILED FOR DIVORCE IN
2008.
LANZA LIVED WITH HIS MOTHER IN
AN UPSCALE PART OF THE CITY.
NEIGHBORSNEIGHBORS WHO KNEW THEY
ARE STUNNED.
>> IT'S LIKE A NORMAL, EVERYBODY
ELSE IN THIS NEIGHBORHOOD.
DECORATE THE HOUSE, AND THE
HOUSE IS ALWAYS PRISTINE AND
JUST LIKE ANY OTHER HOUSE WIFE.
>> OTHER NEWTOWN RESIDENTS ARE
STILL STRUGGLING TO DEAL WITH
THE TREMENDOUS LOSS.
MANY SAY THEY FEEL HOPELESS.
OTHERS NOW FEAR FOR THEIR OWN
FAMILY'S SAFETY.
>> THEY -- I HAVE A DAUGHTER WHO
IS AN ADULT AND SHE IS A FOURTH
GRADE ELEMENTARY COOL -- I'M
SORRY -- TEACHER, AND SHE COULD
BE IN JEOPARDY FOR HER ENTIRE
LIFE NOW, AND IT'S VERY HARD FOR
ME TO -- HAVING A DIFFICULT TIME
PROCESSING THIS NOW.
>> IN ADDITION TO VIGILS BEING
HELD ACROSS CONNECTICUT THERE
IRVARIOUS SIGNS OF SUPPORT FOR
THE VICTIMS AND THEIR FAMILIES,
INCLUDING THIS BANNER HANGING
FROM A WINDOW IN NEWTOWN THAT
READ, HUG A TEACHER TODAY.
>>> IN ALAMEDA, PEOPLE ARE
MOTHERING THE VICTIMS OF THE
SHOOTING.
-- PEOPLE ARE MOURNING THE
VICTIMS OF THE SHOOTING.
HERE'S A LOOK AT ONE HOFF THE
SEVERAL VIGILS THAT HAVE COME
TOGETHER TODAY IN THE BAY AREA.
REPORTER: THIS VIGIL IS JUST
ABOUT TO BEGIN.
I TALKED FOR JUST A FEW MINUTES
WITH THE ORGANIZER.
SHE SAYS SHE IS ACTUALLY QUITE
SURPRISED BY THE RESPONSESES SHE
GOT LAST NIGHT AS SHE SENT OUT
THE E-MAIL ALERT.
SHE SAYS SHE IS EXPECTING 40
PEOPLE TO TURN OUT TO THIS
EVENT, AND IF YOU CONSIDER THAT
THIS IS A PRETTY DRIZZLY AND
COLD EVENING, THAT WOULD BE A
VERY GOOD RESPONSE.
AMONG THOSE WHO ARE HERE, IS A
LOCAL PASTOR, LAURA ROSE.
SHE SAYS SHE ALSO HAS FAMILY IN
CONNECTICUT.
IN FACT TWO OF HER COUSINS WERE
AMONG THOSE WHO WERE AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
YESTERDAY, AND THEY MANAGED TO
ESCAPE.
NOW, I WILL BE TALKING WITH HER
A LITTLE LATER.
THE ORGANIZER OF THE VIGIL TELLS
ME THE TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT
HAS SEEMED TO TOUCH A NERVE
BECAUSE THERE ARE SEVERAL
SIMILAR VIGILS BEING ORGANIZED
ACROSS THE COUNTRY JUST LIKE
THIS ONE, AND THIS ONE IS JUST
ABOUT TO BEGIN AS IT IS IN
PROGRESS, OBVIOUSLY, WE'LL BE
STAYING HERE AND WE'LL HAVE MORE
DETAILS ON THIS ONE COMING UP A
LITTLE LATER ON IN THE EVENING.
REPORTING LIVE IN ALAMEDA,
SERGIO QUINTANA.
ABC-7 NEWS.
>> Ama: THE UNITED WAY OF
WESTERN CONNECTICUT HAS STARTED
A DONATION DRIVE FOR THE VICTIMS
OF THE SHOOTING.
THERE'S A LINK TO THE WEB PAGE
AS ABC7NEWS.COM.
JUST CLICK ON "SEE IT ON TV".
YOU CAN ALSO POST THIS BADGE TO
YOUR FACEBOOK WALL, SILENT SHOW
OF SUPPORT FOR EVERYONE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
IT'S AVAILABLE AT FACE
BOOK.com/ABC-7 NEWS.
>>> THE BAY AREA, AUTHORITIES IN
SAN FRANCISCO AND OAKLAND ARE
WORKING TO GET GUNS OFF THE
STREETS.
WE'RE LIVE FROM SAN FRANCISCO
HALL OF JUSTICE WHERE A LOOK AT
THE WEAPONS RECOVERED TODAY.
REPORTER: WE JUST LEARNED THAT
ACTUALLY 425 GUNS WERE BOUGHT
BACK TODAY.
WHAT MADE THIS PROGRAM UNIQUE IS
IT WAS FUNDED BY AN ANONYMOUS
DOOR KNOW, GIVING ENOUGH MONEY
TO GET 500 GUNS OFF THE STREETS.
>> MORE THAN 200 PEOPLE BRAVED
LONG LINES AND COLD TEMPERATURES
TO TURN IN THEIR GUNS HERE AT
THE SAN FRANCISCO OMEGA BOYS
CLUB.
MANY WERE BROUGHT HERE BY THE
SAME TRAGEDY.
THE MASS MURDER OF 20 CHILDREN
IN CONNECTICUT.
>> IT HIT ME PRETTY STRONG.
>> THAT WHY YOU BROUGHT THE GUN?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
I NEVER THOUGHT ABOUT GETTING
RID OF THEM.
>> HE IS A VIETNAM VET.
HE SAYS HE AND HIS WIFE SOBBED
WHILE WATCHING THE NEWS.
>> SEEING WHAT HAPPENED
YESTERDAY, WE GOT TO GIVE --
KIDS NOW DAY GOODS THROUGH.
REPORTER: THE GUN BUYBACK WAS
FUNDED BY AN ANONYMOUS DONOR.
THEY CONTACTED THE OMEGA BOYS
CLUB IN SAN FRANCISCO.
THE DIRECTOR SAYS THE TURNOUT
SHOWS BOTH COMMUNITIES CARE
ABOUT GUN VIOLENCE.
>> WHEN THE COMMUNITY SAYS
ENOUGH IS ENOUGH, THINK YOU GOT
A GOOD CHANCE WITH SOMETHING
LIKE THIS.
REPORTER: IN OAKLAND PEOPLE
LINED UP IN CARS AT 6:00 A.M. TO
TURN IN GUNS AT ST. BENEDICT'S
CHURCH.
THIS IS WHERE THIS THE OAKLAND
POLICE WERE BUYING THE GUNS.
>> WE HAVE EVERY EXPECTATION TO
EXCEED OUR EXPECTATIONS.
>> THE INITIAL TARGET WAS TAKE
5G HUNDRED GUNS OFF THE STREET.
A FINANCIAL INCENTIVE HELPED
BRING THESE PEOPLE OUT.
>> WELL, THE MONEY.
>> MONEY.
>> $200 WAS PAID FOR EACH HAND
GUN OR RIFLE, A LIMIT OF THREE
WEAPONS FOR EACH RESIDENT, AND
PEOPLE HAD TO PROVE THEY RESIDED
IN THE CITY BUYING THE GUNS.
OTHERS WHO WAITED IN LINE WERE
LIKE LEE, WHO TURNED IN AN
ANTIQUE RIFLE AND WOULD HAND
GUNS.
HIS MOTIVATION WAS PERSONAL
SAFETY.
>> JUST GETTING THEM OUT OF THE
HOUSE.
JUST DON'T NEED THEM.
DON'T USE THEM.
REPORTER: NOW, OAKLAND POLICE
HAVE BEEN ASKED BY THE SANTA
CLARA COUNTY DISTRICT ATTORNEY'S
OFFICE HOW TO START THE SAME
PROGRAM THE SOUTH BAY.
BOTH OAKLAND AND SAN FRANCISCO
POLICE DEPARTMENTS ARE ASKING
THE GOVERNOR TO SEE IF HE CAN
MAKE THE GUN BUYBACK A STATE
PRACTICE WE'RE LIVE IN SAN
FRANCISCO, ABC-7 NEWS.
>> Ama: AS THIS TRAGEDY UNFOLDS,
STAY WITH ABC-7 NEWS FOR
CONTINUING COVERAGE.
YOU CAN RECEIVE URGENT UPDATES
ON YOUR SMART FOAB BY
DOWNLOADING OUR NEWS APP AND
OPTING FOR PUSH NOTIFICATIONS.
>> LET'S GET A FIRST LOOK AT THE
WEATHER.
>> Leigh: VERY COLD SHOWERS
ACROSS THE BAY AREA.
LIVE DOPPLER 7HD HAS A GOOD
HANDLE ON THEM AND WE'LL TAKE A
LOOK AT THAT COMING UP.
>> Ama: HILLARY CLINTON IS BEING
MONITORED BY DOCTORS.
WHY SHE FAINTED AND HIT HER
HEAD.
>> THE TWINKIE COULD BE BROUGHT
BACK FROM EXTINCTION.
BIG PLAYERS
You know how much Grandma
wanted to be here
for your fist Christmas?
You see
Grandma lives waaaay down here,
and you live way up here.
Brian, your cousin, he's
a little bit older than you,
he lives here, in Chicago.
And your Aunt Lisa lives here,
in Baltimore.
Uncle Earnie?
Waaay out in Hawaii.
But don't you worry,
we will always be together
for Christmas.
[ Male Announcer ]
Being together
is the best part
of the holidays
and Cheerios is happy
to be part of the family.
You just ate Dallas!
>> Ama: TWO PEOPLE ARE IN
CUSTODY FOR A SHOOTING THAT
INJURED FOUR PEOPLE AT 7:30 THIS
MORNING.
POLICE AREN'T SURE WHAT LED THE
SHOOTING.
THE FOUR PEOPLE INJURED ARE ALL
EXPECTED TO SURVIVE.
>>> WE LEARNED THE NAMES OF THE
PEOPLE WHO DIED IN FRIDAY'S
CRASH ON NORTHBOUND 280 IN
REDWOOD CITY.
WE WERE OVER THE SCENE AFTER THE
ACCIDENT HAPPENED JUST AFTER
3:00.
AUTHORITIES SAY THE LEXUS WAS IN
THE CENTER MEDIAN BECAUSE OF A
FLAT TIRE.
THE DRIVER OF A BLACK VOLKSWAGEN
SLAMMED INTO THE LEXUS AS A HIGH
RATE OF SPEED.
THREE PEOPLE IN THE LEXUS WERE
CALLED.
A 48-YEAR-OLD, 28-YEAR-OLD, AND
A 21-YEAR-OLD.
A 56-YEAR-OLD SUFFERED MODERATE
INJURIES.
82-YEAR-OLD G.A. SMITH WILL BE
CHARGED WITH FELONY MANSLAUGHTER
AFTER HE IS RELEASED FROM THE
HOSPITAL.
>> THE TWINKIE COULD BE COMING
BACK.
WE'LL LOOK AT THE BIG PLAYERS IN
THE FOOD AND GROCERY INDUSTRY
VYING FOR THE HOSTESS BRAND.
>> AND LEIGH GLASER HAS YOUR
FORECAST AFTER THE
>> ABC-7 LEARN THAT PRESIDENT
OBAMA WILL NOMINATE SENATOR JOHN
KERRY TO BE SECRETARY OF STATE.
THE MASSACHUSETTS DEMOCRAT
BECAME THE FRONT RUNNER WHEN
U.N. AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE
REMOVED HER NAME FROM
CONSIDERATION.
LAWMAKERS WERE UNHAPPY AFTER
STATEMENTS BEEN THE ATTACK IN
BENGHAZI.
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON IS SET TO RETIRE IN THE
NEXT FEW WEEKS.
SHE IS ACTUALLY RECOVERING AT
HOME AFTER A CONCUSSION CAUSED
BY WHEN SHE FAINTED.
DEHYDRATION FROM A STOMACH VIRUS
CAUSED CLINTON TO PASS OUT.
AN AIDE SAYS SHE WILL WORK FROM
HOME NEXT WEEK.
CLINTON IS NOT EXPECTED TO
TESTIFY AT CONGRESSIONAL
HEARINGS THURSDAY ON HE BENGHAZI
TERROR ATTACKS.
>>> SOME BIG NAMES ARE LOOKING
TO GET IN ON THE HOSTESS BRAND
BUSINESS.
BLOOMBERG REPORTS GROWINGER AND
WAL-MART ARE AMONG IN 24
COMPANIES BIDDING FOR THE
TWIRVEGIE MAKER'S ASSETS.
A THE LARGEST BREAD-BAKING
COMPANY IN THE WORLD IS ALSO
INTERESTED, ALONG WITH FOOD
PRODUCERS, CONAGRA AND FLOWERS
FOODS AND THE BAKER OF LITTLE
DEBBIE SNACKS, HOSTESS, FILED
FOR BANKRUPTCY AMID A NATIONWIDE
WORKER STRIKE.
BIDDING COULD GO AS HIGH AS A
BILLION DOLLARS.
>> LET'S CHECK ON OUR WEATHER
WITH LEIGH GLASER.
>> Leigh: HI THERE, EVERYONE.
A COLD RAIN HAS SETTLED OVER THE
BAY AREA.
THE CLOUDS TRAPPING A POOL OF
COLD AIR CLOSE TO THE SURFACE.
THIS IS LOOKING WEST.
THE BAY BRIDGE HERE, A MERCKY
VIEW AS THE FOG IS STARTING TO
SETTLE IN AS WELL.
LET'S GET RIGHT TO LIVE DOPPLER
7HD.
THOSE IN THE NORTH BAY, COLD
SHOWERS OFF AND ON ALL MORNING
LONG, YOU CAN SEE THAT MOST OF
THE ACTIVITY NOW HAS SLIPPED TO
THE SOUTH OF SAN FRANCISCO SO
THE SOUTH OF SAN JOSE IN THE
NORTH BAY, STARTING TO SEE DISH
WON'T SAY PARTIAL CLEARING BUT
SOME OF THIS IS VERY LIGHT,
STARTING TO EASE UP.
BUT POINTS SOUTHWARD AND
EASTWARD, YOU'RE STILL GOING TO
FIND LIGHT RAIN PUSHING THROUGH
THE LIVERMORE VALLEY AREA,
TOWARDS NILES ROAD, AND DOWN
TOWARDS THE GILROY AREA,
HOLLISTER, MORGAN HILL, THAT'S
WHERE THE LIGHT TO MODERATE RAIN
BANDS FILTER THROUGH, AND ALL OF
THIS WILL SLOWLY PLACE BACK
OVERNIGHT.
WE'LL KEEP A CHANCE OF SHOWERS
IN THE FORECAST.
TEMPERATURES RIGHT NOW, COOL IN
THE MID-TO-UPPER 40s.
IN ALL LOCATIONS.
COLD SHOWERS OVERNIGHT.
ALSO A POSSIBILITY OF SNOW
COMING DOWN ON HIGHER PEAKS.
HAMILTON THIS AFTERNOON
REPORTING A LIGHT DUSTING SO
IT'S THERE WITH ALL THIS COLD
AIR IN PLACE.
SOME CLEARING BY TOMORROW
AFTERNOON BEFORE ANOTHER ROUND
OF RAIN MOVES IN LATE TOMORROW
NIGHT.
OVERNIGHT TEMPERATURES IN THE
NORTH BAY IN THE MID-TO-UPPER
30s.
40s, MID-TO 4R0s ELSEWHERE,
AND HERE'S A LOOK AT THE STORM
SYSTEM.
YOU CAN SEE THE COLD FRONT
MAKING ITS WAY ACROSS THE BAY
AREA, IT'S FALLING APART BUT
WILL BRING US MORE MOISTURE OFF
AND ON TONIGHT.
THE COLD SHOWERS WILL CONTINUE,
IN SOME OF THE HIGHER
ELEVATIONS, COULD POSSIBLY SEE A
LITTLE SNOW.
HERE'S A LOOK BY SATURDAY NIGHT,
STARTING AT 10:00, MOST OF THE
ACTIVITY TO THE SOUTH AND THEN
TOMORROW MORNING, AT 5:00 A.M.,
WE'LL LOOK FOR THE FEW MORE
LINGERING SHOWERS.
A LITTLE BIT OF CLEARING
TOMORROW AFTERNOON, YOU'LL SEE
THERE, BY 2:00, 3:00, FEW MORE
STRAY SHOWERS MOVE IN LOOKS LIKE
TOMORROW NIGHT, AFTER THE
10:00 TIME FRAME, THAT'S WHEN
ANOTHER BAND -- THIS IS
9:00 P.M. -- ANOTHER BATCH OF
RAIN WILL MOVE IN AND THAT WILL
KEEP US WET ON MONDAY.
BY THE WAY, WINTER WEATHER
ADVISORY FOR SNOW ABOVE THE
2500-FOOT LEVEL IS IN PLACE FOR
THE LAKE COUNTY AREA, THE HIGHER
ELEVATIONS.
EXPECT TWO TO FOUR INCHES OF
SNOW POSSIBLE ABOVE THAT SNOW
LEVEL LINE, AND THAT COULD
CREATE SLICK ROADS, CHAINS COULD
BE POSSIBLE, AND ALSO SOME
TRAVEL DELAYS.
THAT IS IN PLACE UNTIL
4:00 TOMORROW.
SO, HERE'S A LOOK AT OUR HIGHS
FOR TOMORROW.
COME UP MAYBE A FEW DEGREES AND
SEE A LITTLE MORE SUNSHINE-BUT
IT'S GOING TO BE MID-TO UPPER
40s TO LOW 50s ACROSS MUCH
OF THE BAY AREA.
SAN FRANCISCO, 50.
53 FOR LIVERMORE, SEE SCATTERED
SHOWERS SOUTH OF MORTGAGE GAP
HILL TOMORROW BUT GILROY WARMING
TO 55, AND WATSONVILLE 53.
THE AccuWeather SEVEN-DAY
FORECAST, ACTIVE.
MONDAY, ANOTHER RAIN CHANCE,
IT'S LIKELY.
TUESDAY REMARKS SLIGHT BREAK,
WEDNESDAY, FEW MORE LINGERING
SHOWERS.
A LARGER STORM WILL MOVE IN
THURSDAY NIGHT, LINGERING INTO
FRIDAY AND SATURDAY.
SO LOOKS LIKE IT WILL BE WET THE
LATTER PART OF NEXT WEEK.
>> Ama: MIKE SHUMANN IS HERE
WITH A PREVIEW OF SPORTS AND
COLLEGE FOOTBALL.
>> Mike: THE COLLEGE FOOTBALL
BOWL SEASON KICKED OFF TODAY.
AND THE WARRIORS ARE IN ATLANTA.
WITH A WIN THEY WOULD COME HOME
You know how much Grandma
wanted to be here
for your fist Christmas?
You see
Grandma lives waaaay down here,
and you live way up here.
Brian, your cousin, he's
a little bit older than you,
he lives here, in Chicago.
And your Aunt Lisa lives here,
in Baltimore.
Uncle Earnie?
Waaay out in Hawaii.
But don't you worry,
we will always be together
for Christmas.
[ Male Announcer ]
Being together
is the best part
of the holidays
and Cheerios is happy
to be part of the family.
You just ate Dallas!
>> THE WARRIORS HAVE BEEN ON A
ROAD TRIP THAT ENDS IN ATLANTA.
THEY WON THE FIRST FIVE
STRAIGHT, INCLUDING KNOCKING OFF
THE MIAMI HEAT.
ORE LAB DOUGH HASN'T THEM THE
FIRST LOSS LAST NIGHT.
SEE IF THEY CAN COME HOME 6-1.
WARRIORS OFF TO THE BEST START
SINCE THEN '91 SEASON.
SETH CURRY, AND LEE LAYERS IT
IN, HARRISON BARNES LOOKING
STRONG, 2-2 BEYOND THE ARC, 1 IN
THE FIRST HALF.
THE FOLLOW-UP ONE-HANDED SLAM
WE'LL HAVE MORE HIGHLIGHTS
COMING UP AT 6:00.
>> TO COLLEGE HOOPS, STANFORD
MEN FACING UC DAVIS IN A
NONCONFERENCE MATCHUP.
FIRST GAME IN 13 DAY FOR THE
CARDINAL.
EXAMS THEY CALL THEM.
ONLY TWO DAVIS PLAYERS HILT
DOUBLE LAYOFFS, STANFORD NO
LOSS.
CARDINAL LED AT THE HALF.
DWIGHT PAUL LED ALL CARDINAL
PLAYERS.
FOR THE MONSTER JAM.
CARDINAL WIN, 75-52.
>> COLLEGE FOOTBALL BOWL SEASON
KICKED OFF IN ALBUQUERQUE WITH
ARIZONA AND NEVADA FACING OFF.
THE FIRST OF 35 BOWL GAMES IN
THE NEXT 22 GAMES.
WHAT A GAME.
THIRD QUARTER.
NEVADA QUARTERBACK DOUBLE FAKES,
FINDS A WIDE-OPEN RICHIE TURNER.
WOLFPACK UP 10.
ARIZONA ONLIES BACK.
14:36 TO PLAY.
48-42 NEVADA.
THE ENSUING KICKOFF, THE ONSIDE
KICK, GET IT, MARCH DOWN THE
FIELD.
THIRD T.D. PASS OF THE GAME
OTHER.
>> UTAH STATE FACING TOLEDO IN
THE IDAHO POTATO BOWL.
FEET TON, 62 YARDS TOUCHDOWN,
FINISHED WITH 270 YARDS IN THE
AIR.
UTAH STATE WINS THE ALWAYS
POPULAR IDAHO POTATO BOWL,
41-15.
>>> THE DIVISION 2 CHAMPIONSHIP
GAME, WENT FROM TATE'S OPENING
KICKOFF.
TO HIS OWN FOUR, UP THE MIDDLE.
96 YARDS.
7-0 VALDOSTA JUST LIKE THAT.
STILL IN THE FIRST.
BLAZERS, O'NEILL, FOURTH AND
ONE, 24 YARDS TO THE END ZONE.
O'NEILL, 141 YARDS ON 24
CARRIES.
VALDOSTA WINS THEIR FIRST
NATIONAL CHAMPIONSHIP, ENDING
THEIR SEASON 12-2.
>> HIGH SCHOOL FOOTBALL, MARINE
AND MADDISON FOR THE CIF
DIVISION THREE CHAMPIONSHIP GAME
IN CARSON, CALIFORNIA.
FOURTH QUARTER, MARIN CATHOLIC
QUARTERBACK HEADED TO CAL, THREW
FOUR T.D.'S ON THE DAY.
HIT AT THE LINE AND INTEREST
OTHER THE HANDS HOFF HE WILD
RECEIVER.
MADISON ANSWERS ON THE ENSUING
DRIVE.
CORMIER RAN FOR -- MADISON IS
THE DIVISION 3 CHAMPION.
>> COMING UP AT 6:00, MAJOR
UPSET IN COLLEGE HOOPS AND MORE
FROM THE WARRIORS, HOPE TO SEE
YOU THEN.
>> Ama: THANK YOU, MIKE, GRAB
SOME WATER.
>> A SPECIAL GUEST JOINS US FOR
A LITTLE HOLIDAY CHEER.
THAT'S NEXT
You know how much Grandma
wanted to be here
for your fist Christmas?
You see
Grandma lives waaaay down here,
and you live way up here.
Brian, your cousin, he's
a little bit older than you,
he lives here, in Chicago.
And your Aunt Lisa lives here,
in Baltimore.
Uncle Earnie?
Waaay out in Hawaii.
But don't you worry,
we will always be together
for Christmas.
[ Male Announcer ]
Being together
is the best part
of the holidays
and Cheerios is happy
to be part of the family.
You just ate Dallas!
>> COMING UP IN HALF HOUR AT
6:00, A MESS AFTER A DEADLY
ACCIDENT ON A BAY AREA ROAD.
WE'LL TELL YOU HOW TRAFFIC IS
MOVING.
A DIFFERENT KIND OF MESS ON
HIGHWAY 1.
WHY A CLOSED HIGHWAY COULD SAY
CLOSED INDEFINITELY, AND WE'LL
BE BACK TO BRING YAW OWL OF THAT
AT 6:00.
ACCEPT HAD A -- SANTA HAD A
SPECIAL ESCORT AT SAN MATEO
MEDICAL CENTER.
BIKERS FROM THE GOLDEN GATE
HARLEY CLUB RODE WITH SANTA TO
THE HOSPITAL.
VOLUNTEERS AND STAFF MET THE
RIDERS WHO PLACED THE GIFTS
UNDER A HOLIDAY TREE IN THE MAIN
LOBBY.
THEY'LL BE DISTRIBUTED TO 6,000
CHILDREN WHO RECEIVE CARE AT THE
MEDICAL CENTER DURING THE
HOLIDAYS.
IT'S THE 23rd YEAR THE BIKERS
HAVE MADE THE HOLIDAY TOY RUN,
AND IN THE RAIN TODAY, TOO.
>> Mike: ONLY SANTA CAN HANG
WITH THE HARLEY RIDERS.
>> Ama: THAT DOES IT FOR US AT
5:00.
Captioned by Closed Captioning
Services Inc.
>>> THIS IS A SPECIAL EDITION OF
"WORLD NEWS."
TONIGHT, TRAGEDY AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE NATION SHAKEN BY THE
DEADLIEST ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
SHOOTING IN OUR HISTORY.
THIS EVENING, THE HEARTBREAKING
DETAILS NOW EMERGING.
THE CLASSROOMS TARGETED.
THE YOUNG FACES BEING REVEALED.
>> WHEN THE POLICEMAN CAME IN TO
GET US, HE TOLD US TO CLOSE OUR
EYES.
>> AND RUN.
>>> FOR THE FIRST TIME A
COUNSELOR INSIDE THAT FIREHOUSE
WHERE PARENTS REALIZED THEIR
CHILDREN WEREN'T COMING OUT.
>> IT WAS LIKE WATCHING
SOMETHING THAT WASN'T REAL.
>>> AND TONIGHT, THE PORTRAIT OF
THE SHOOTER EMERGING.
NEW IMAGES FROM ONE OF THE
STUDENTS THAT KNEW HIM.