TO, UH, HAVE TO
DEAL WITH OUR CHAMPION, THOUGH,
WHO IS AN EXCELLENT PLAYER,
SO GOOD LUCK
TO ALL THREE OF YOU.
LET'S GO TO WORK RIGHT NOW,
SHALL WE?
HERE COMES THE JEOPARDY! ROUND
FOR YOU,
AND TODAY WE HAVE
THESE CATEGORIES AWAITIN..
(laughter)
AND WE'LL GIVE YOU
THE DEFINITION...
"I" IN QUOTATION MARKS...
AND NOTICE THE SPELLING THERE.
JASON, START.
BOWL GAME CITIES FOR $200.
WHAT IS ATLANTA?
BOWL GAME CITIES FOR $400.
WHAT IS SAN ANTONIO?
BOWL GAME FOR $600.
WHAT IS TEMPE?
BOWL GAME FOR $800.
WHAT IS NASHVILLE?
BOWL GAME FOR $1,000.
WHAT IS SAN DIEGO?
YOU ARE A FOOTBALL FAN,
MY FRIEND,
AND YOU'VE MADE IT
PAY OFF HANDSOMELY,
BUT WE'RE OUT
OF BOWL CITIES.
"I" KNOW IT FOR $200.
WHAT IS IHOP?
"I" KNOW IT, $400.
WHAT ARE ICONS?
"I" KNOW IT, $600.
WHAT IS IZOD?
"I" KNOW IT FOR $800.
WHAT IS IBERIA?
"I" KNOW IT FOR $1,000.
WHAT ARE THE ISOTOPES?
UM, "WEBSTER'S" FOR $200.
WHAT IS A KAYAK?
"WEBSTER'S" FOR $400.
WHAT IS FORECAST?
"WEBSTER'S" FOR $600.
WHAT IS THOU?
UH, "WEBSTER'S" FOR $800.
WHAT IS BUT?
UH, "WEBSTER'S," $1,000.
WHAT ARE HALCYON?
THAT'S $1,000 MORE FOR YOU,
AND IT TAKES US
TO OUR FIRST COMMERCIAL BREAK,
SO TAKE IT EASY
FOR A FEW MOMENTS
WHILE WE PAUSE
FOR THESE MESSAGES.
IS ISCONSIN.
SO TAKE IT EASY
FOR A FEW MOMENTS
TRAVELING CAN BE
A PROBLEM SOMETIMES.
I UNDERSTAND YOU WERE
ONCE ON SAFARI IN KENYA,
U AND A FRIEND
DECIDED TO DO SOMETHING...
NOT SO SMART.
THAT'S RIGHT. THERE--
OUR CLASS WAS DIVIDED UP INTO,
LIKE, SMALL GROUPS ON BUSES,
AND WE CAME ACROSS A MALE LION
JUST RESTING IN THE SAVANNA,
AND MY FRIEND DECIDED
THAT WASN'T GOOD ENOUGH
AND WANTED AN ACTION PHOTO,
SO HE STARTED THROWING PEBBLES.
AND THE LION SWATTED 'EM AWAY,
SWATTED 'EM AWAY--
EVENTUALLY HAD ENOUGH, I GUESS,
AND GOT UP
AND STARTED CHARGING THE BUS,
AND THE DRIVER AND ALL OF US
WERE NOT TOO THRILLED WITH THAT,
SO...
LEAVE THEM ALONE.
IT'S A GOOD THING
THAT YOU WERE STILL ON THE BUS.
IF YOU HAD GOTTEN OUT ON FOOT,
IT MIGHT HAVE HAD.THEY WOULDN'T.
DIRE CONSEQUENCES.
KATHLEEN SCHULTZ
FROM PORTLAND, OREGON...
I WOULD LIKE YOU--
I'M A BIG FAN OF TIRAMISU,
AND I UNDERSTAND YOU HAVE
A SPECIAL RECIPE, SO...
I DO.
TELL--TELL ME ABOUT THAT.
WELL, IT'S VERY SIMPLE,
BUT IT REQUIRES KAHLÚA.
THANK YOU.
AND ONE YEAR, UM,
I HAD MY 21-YEAR-OLD SON
DO THAT PART OF IT,
THE COFFEE AND KAHLÚA...
MM-HMM.
AND HE USED
A LITTLE TOO MUCH KAHLÚA,
AND WE GOT THE DONORS
VERY TIPSY.
AND, UH, DID THEY CONTRIBUTE,
UH, A LITTLE MORE THAN USUAL?
NO, 'CAUSE THEY'D ALREADY PAID.
WE JUST HAD TO POUR
LOTS OF ESPRESSO DOWN 'EM
TO GET 'EM HOME.
OH, OKAY.
JASON KELLER IS A TUTOR.
HE IS OUR CHAMPION,
AND HE--
ONE OF HIS CLAIMS TO FAME,
FOLKS,
IS SOMETHING
YOU WOULD NEVER GUESS.
YOU HAVE BEEN MISTAKEN
FOR WHICH SEMI-FAMOUS PERSON?
ZULU, QUEEN OF THE DWARF PEOPLE.
(laughter)
WHO IS ZULU,
QUEEN OF THE DWARF PEOPLE?
UH, AT LS I UNDERSTAND,
I'M A FAN OF THE "GOLDEN GIRLS,"
AND IT WAS A NAME THAT
SOPHIA USED ON ONE EPISODE,
UH, WHEN SHE WAS CHECKING IN
TO A HOSPITAL,
AND, UH... AND, UH,
ROSE WAS TAKING HER NAME,
AND SHE SARCASTICALLY SAID,
"ZULU,
QUEEN OF THE DWARF PEOPLE,"
AND IT ENDED UP HER BRA.
OKAY. GOOD.
KATHLEEN, YOU HAVE COMMAND
OF THE BOARD RIGHT NOW.
"QUEEN OF THE ZULU PEOPLE."
ALL RIGHT.
YEAH, DWARF PEOPLE. GO.
MAKE A SELECTION.
BUMPER STICKER HUMOR FOR $200.
WHAT IS HONK?
HUMOR FOR $400.
WHAT IS CHEESE?
HUMOR FOR $600.
WHAT IS SPENT MONEY?
CHARGED IT.
YEAH, WE'LL ACCEPT THAT.
WENT SHOPPING.
GOOD GIRL. GO.
BUMPER STICKER HUMOR, $800.
WHAT ARE CLOWNS?
BUMPER STIUMOR
FOR $1,000.
WHAT IS HAUNT ME?
ANOTHER $1,000 FOR YOU.
DOCTOR, LAWYER,
NATIVE AMERICAN LEADER.
FOR?
$200.
WHAT IS MAYO?
DOCTOR, LAWYER FOR $400.
SEEN HERE, THE MONUMENT
THIS LAKOTA INDIAN
IS IN THE BLACK HILLS
OF SOUTH DAKOTA.
WHAT IS CRAZY HORSE?
DOCTOR, LAWYER, $600.
AND YOUR FIRST OPPORTUNITY TO
TAKE THE LEAD AWAY FROM JASON.
I'LL BET $2,000, ALEX.
$2,000? THAT'LL PUT YOU CLOSE.
HERE IS THE CLUE...
WHO IS...
SOTOMAYOR?
NO, YOU PICKED
THE WRONG ONE.
SHE'S NOW ON THE SUPREME COURT.
KAGAN.
ALL RIGHT, YOU'RE AT $2,400.
GO AGAIN.
DOCTOR, LAWYER, $800.
WHO IS CLARENCE DARROW?
HE'S THE ATTORNEY.
DOCTOR, LAWYER FOR $1,000.
WHO IS MUDD?
DR. SAMUEL MUDD.
LET'S GET SIRIUS, $200.
WHAT ARE LIGHT-YEARS?
LET'S GET SIRIUS, $400.
WHAT'S A BINARY?
SIRIUS FOR $600.
WHAT'S A WHITE DWARF?
$800.
WHAT IS MAGNITUDE?
AND NOW THE LAST CLUE...
WHO IS ISIS?
THAT'S $1,000 MORE FOR YOU,
AND YOU'RE STILL IN THIRD PLACE,
UNFORTUNATELY, OR FORTUNATELY,
BECAUSE IN DOUBLE JEOPARDY!
YOU GET TO SELECT FIRST,
AFTER THIS.
SPONSORED IN PART BY...
UNFORTUNATELY, OR FORTUNATELY,
ÑSñACLOSED CAPTIONINGPARDY!
OUR CHAMPION, JASON,
GOT OFF TO A VERY GOOD START,
SO IT'S UP
TO KATHLEEN AND DEREK,
WHO PICKS FIRST TO DO
SOME CATCHING UP.
THE CATEGORIES FOR THIS ROUND...
"GREEN" IN QUOTATION MARKS.
THAT SOUNDS LIKE FUN.
DEREK?
LET'S TRY COUNTRIES' LOCAL NAMES
FOR $400.
WHAT IS POLAND?
LOCAL NAMES FOR $800.
WHAT IS JAPAN?
COUNTRIES', $1,200.
WHAT IS HUNGARY?
LOCAL NAMES FOR $1,600.
WILL THAT BE AN ADVANTAGE?
WE'RE GONNA FIND OUT RIW
HOW MUCH OF THAT $10,800
ARE YOU GOING TO PUT AT RISK?
$5,000, PLEASE.
ALL RIGHGHT NOHERE IS THE C.
WHAT IS GREECE?
GREECE IS RIGHT.
PIECE OF CAKE FOR YOU,
JASON.
L NAMES FOR $2,000.
WHAT IS FINLAND?
ACTRESSES FOR $400.
HERE'S GLENN CLOSE
WITH THE CLUE...
WHAT IS "FATAL ATTRACTION"?
AND SHE WAS SO GOOD IN THAT.
SCARED ME.
CHRISTMASTIME IN NEW YORK
FOR $400.
ALL RIGHT, HERE'S JIMMY
TO START IT OFF.
IT MAY NOT BE CROWDED
RIGHT NOW,
BUT COME NEW YEAR'S EVE,
THERE'LL BE
RE REVELERS GATHERED
IN THIS FESTIVE
NEW YORK CITY LOCATION
WHERE THE BALL HAS DROPPED
FOR MORE THAN 100 YEARS.
CHRISTMASTIME FOR $800.
BACK TO JIMMY.
TAKE SOMEONE SPECIAL
TO RADIO CITY MUSIC HALL'S
CHRISTMAS SPECTACULAR
TO SEE A LINEUP
OF 36 OF THESE PERFORM
WHO ARE THE ROCKETTES?
CHRISTMASTIME, $1,200.
SARAH NOW.
FIGHT ERS.
OWDS
ON THIS FAMOUS AVENUE
SARAH NOW.
FOR QUALITY GIFTS
FROM THE LIKES OF TIFFANY,
BERGDORF GOODMAN,
AND LOUIS VUITTON.
WHAT IS 5th AVENUE?
YOU NOTICE JIMMY WAS
LOOKING AT THE ROCKETTES,
AND SARAH WAS SHOPPING.
GO AGAIN.
(laughter)
CHRISTMASTIME IN NEW YORK,
$1,600.
LET'S GO BACK TO SARAH.
HERE'S A CHRISTMAS COCKTAIL
THAT'S SURE TO WARM YOUR HEART.
MADE WITH MELON-FLAVORED
MIDORI LIQUEUR,
IT'S NAMED
FOR THIS DR. SEUSS CHARACTER.
WHO IS THE GRINCH?
CHRISTMASTIME FOR $2,000.
IT'S A VIDEO,
AND YOU ALREADY HAVE $18,200.
LET'S TRY $5,000 AGAIN, PLEASE.
$5,000 AGAIN. ALL RIGHT.
HERE'S JIMMY THE.
GINGERBREAD MEN
AND HANDMADE ORNAMENTS
ARE BUT A FEW OF THE ITEMS
OFFERED AT THE HOLIDAY MARKET
AT THIS FAMOUS CIRCLE
NAMED FOR AN ITALIAN EXPLOIS TM
WHAT IS COLUMBUS CIRCLE?
YOU ARE RIGHT,
AND YOU MOVE UP TO $23,200,
AND WE'RE NOT EVEN
HALFWAY THROUGH THIS ROUND.
GO AGAIN.
EXERCISE & FITNESS FOR $400.
WHAT IS THE CORE?
ACTRESSES FOR $800, PLEASE.
WHO IS EMMA THOMPSON?
ACTRESSES FOR $1,200.
WHO IS MILA KUNIS?
EXERCISE & FITNESS FOR $800.
WHAT IS AN ELLIPTICAL?
EXERCISE FOR $1,200.
WHAT ARE CURVES?
EXERCISE FOR $1,600.
YOU HAVE TO BE CAREFUL
SWINGING AROUND THIS HEFTY PIECE
OF EQUIPMENT
THAT'S GAINED POPULARITY
RECENTLY.
THAT'S CALLED A KETTLEBELL.
KETTLEBELL. JASON.
UM, GOING GREEN FOR $400.
WHAT IS A GREENHOUSE?
GOING GREEN, $800.
WHAT IS A GREENGROCER?
GOING GREEN, $1,200.
WHAT IS A GREENHORN?
GREEN, $1,600.
WHAT IS A GREENBELT?
GREEN FOR $2,000.
WHAT IS GREENMAIL?
$2,0E FOR YOU.
ACTRESSES, $1,600.
WHO IS NEVE CAMPBELL?
ACTRESSES, $2,000.
A STAR FOR DECADES,
SHE'S SEEN HERE
WHO IS BARBARA STANWYCK?
FACE BOOKS, $400.
"FACE-LIFT SOURCEBOOK"?
SORRY.
WHAT IS--
WHAT IS LIFT?
KATHLEEN--
MOMENTARY FORGETFULNESS THERE.
GO AGAIN, JASON.
FACE BOOK FOR $800.
WHAT IS CR
NO. JASON.
WHAT IS MIRROR?
FACE BOOKS FOR $1,200.
OWD?
WHAT IS MIRROR?
WHAT IS MUSIC?
FACE BOOK, $1,600.
WHAT IS FAMILIAR?
FACE BOOKS, $2,000.
WHAT IS ANATOLIA?
AND NOW
THE LAST $2,000 CLUE...
WHAT IS ZUMBA?
AND YOU'RE RIGHT IN CONTENTION
AGAIN WITH $19,200.
AND DEREK STILL VERY MUCH ALIVE
WITH $8,200.
FINAL JEOPARDY! CATEGORY
FOR THE THREE OF YOU--
FAMOUS BUILDINGS.
THINK ABOUT THAT.
WE'LL RETURN TO REVEAL THE CLUE,
AS WE ALWAYS DO,
FOLLOWING THIS.
OK, IF YOU HAVE COPD LIKE ME,
YOU KNOW IT CAN BE HARD TO
BREATHE, AND HOW THAT FEELS.
WE'LL RETURN TO REVEAL THE CLUE,
COPD INCLUDES CHRONIC
BRONCHITIS AND EMPHYSEMA.
SPIRIVA HELPS CONTROL
LO  MY COPD SY
BY KEEPING MY AIRWAYS
OPEN FOR 24 HOURS.
PLUS, IT REDUCES COPD FLARE-UPS.
MSPIRIVA IS THE ONLY ONCE-DAILY
INHALED COPD MAINTENANCE
TREATMENT THAT DOES BOTH.
SPIRIVA HANDIHALER TIOTROPIUM
BROMIDE INHALATION POWDER
DOES NOT REPLACE FAST-ACTING
INHALERS FOR SUDDEN SYMPTOMS.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU HAVE
KIDNEY PROBLEMS, GLAUCOMA,
TROUBLE URINATING, OR
AN ENLARGED PROSTATE.
THESE MAY WORSEN WITH SPIRIVA.
DISCUSS ALL MEDICINES
YOU TAKE, EVEN EYE DROPS.
STOP TAKING SPIRIVA AND SEEK
IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
IF YOUR BREATHING
SUDDENLY WORSENS,
YOUR THR TONGUE
SWELLS, YOU GET HIVES,
VISION CHANGES OR EYE PAIN,
OR PROBLEMS PASSING URINE.
OTHER SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE
DRY MOUTH AND CONSTIPATION.
NOTHING CAN REVERSE COPD.
SPIRIVA HELPS ME BREATHE BETTER.
(BLOWING SOUND)
ASK YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT SPIRIVA.
THE CATEGORY FOR FINAL JEOPARDY!
AS WE BEGIN THE WEEK
IS FAMOUS BUILDINGS, AND HERE IS
THE CLUE FOR YOU, PLAYERS...
30 SECONDS. GOOD LUCK.
♪
WE'LL START WITH YOU,
DEREK.
YOU WERE IN THIRD PLACE
WITH $8,200,
AND YOU WROTE DOWN
"WHAT IS THE DUOMO?"
SORRY, THAT'S INCORRECT.
COST YOU $8,200.
EVERYTHING YOU HAD.
BOO, HISS.
KATHLEEN, OVER TO YOU NOW.
YOU HAD $19,200,
AND YOUR RESPONSE WAS
RTHENON.
WHAT DID IT COST YOU? $2,700.
ALL RIGHT. INTERESTING WAGER.
YOU STILL HAVETHE PA00
AS WE COME TO JASON KELLER.
WHAT WAS HIS RESPONSE?
HE'S SHAKING HIS HEAD.
HE WASN'T ABLE TO COME UP
WITH IT.
ICOSAG $16,5LD MAKE IT
ALMOST ROUND,
AND WHAT FAMOUS BUILDING
IS ALMOST ROUND?
THE GLOBE THEATRE...
(Jason) OH.
WHERE SHAKESPEARE
PRESENTED HIS PLAYS.
WHAT DID IT COST OUR CHAMPION?
$11,000.
THAT LEAVES HIM
WITH $16,600.
WHAT DID(audience gasps)MPION?
MY GOSH.
WHAT A CLOSE FINISH.
AND HE REMAINS CHAMPION WITH...
AS A 2-DAY TOTAL,
AND WE'LL SAY GOOD-BYE
TO YOU, JASON.
WE'LL SEE YOU TOMORROW.
SO LONG, EVERYBODY.
PROMOTIONAL CONSIDERATION
PROVIDED BY...