GUNMAN.
LANZA FOUND DEAD INSIDE OF THE
SCHOOL, ARMED WITH FOUR WEAPON
WAS A BULLETPROOFED VEST.
ADAM BELIEVED TO HAVE KILLED
HIS MOTHER AT HER HOME.
THIS IS THE SECOND DEADLIEST
SHOOTING IN U.S. HISTORY.
VIRGINIA TECH, THE MOSTç]=tú
DEADLY.
ADAM LANZA'S OLDER BROTHER,
RYAN IS COOPERATING WITH
POLICE.
HE WAS INITIALLY NAMED AS A
SUSPECT IN HAD THIS SHOOTING.
OFFICERS TELLING RORL
RORLT -- REPORTERS HE IS NOT
A SUSPECT.
>> SOME BAY AREA SCHOOLS ARE
TAKING EXTRA PRECAUTIONS,
BRINGING SECURITY TO CAMPUSES.
THIS IS VIDEO FROM SKY 7 HD
OVER LOCKWOOD ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
RESPONSE TO A SHOOTING.
MAKING THEIR POLICE OFFICERS
AVAILABLE AT ANY SCHOOL THAT
WANTEDzqQ2 TRAECHL SECURITY TO.
OFFICER AS SIGNED TO THE SIX
CAMPUSES IN THE DISTRICT.
>> WE NEVER THINK OF THIS
UNSPEAKABLE ACT OF VIOLENCE
BUT IT COULD.
WHICH IS HAVE POLICE HERE IN
THE BAY AREA TRY AS BEST THEY
CAN TO PREPARE.
IN CASE ABC 7 NEWS IS LIVE IN
SAN FRANCISCO TONIGHT WITH
THAT PART OF THE COVERAGE.
VIC?
>> OF COURSE, IT'S BEEN A
DIFFICULT DAY FOR ALL12z SCHOOL
ADMINISTRATORS AND TEACHERS
HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
OFFICERS CONTACTED SCHOOLS IN
ZROIKTS ASK IF THEY NEED
ADDITIONAL HELP.@çAAsóó] wwçó
TEACHERS HERE HAVE BEEN
TRAINED ON HOW TO ADDRESS,
TRAINED TEACHERS ON HOW TO
ADDRESS STUDENTS WHEN ASKING
ABOUT THESE VIOLENT INCIDENTS.
THAT WAS PRETTY MUCH THE SAME
PROTOCOL THEM. SAY THEY HAVE
DRILLS IN PLACE.
SINCE THE MASSACRE, SCHOOLS
HAVE BEEN HANDING DRILLS WITH
POLICE.
SIMULATING SHOOTINGS.
ALL WITH A GOAL OF PREPARING
TEACHERS, STAFF AND STUDENTS
FOR UNTHINKABLE.
IT'S TAUGHT SCHOOLS TO TOUGHEN
SECURITY, RE-EXAMINING HOW TO
RESPOND TO VIOLENCE.é1 ÷
SAN FRANCISCO SCHOOL CHIEF
SAYS EVERY CAMPUS NOW HAS A
SAFETY PLAN AND A CRISIS MAN
YULE.
>> IT HAS MULTIPLE SCENARIOS
FROM INTRUDE DWRORZ GAS LEAKS
TO ELECTRICAL LEAKS TO
EVACUATIONS AND SCHOOLS
PRACTICE THE SAFETY PLANS
REGULARLY.
>> HE AND OTHER SCHOOL
OFFICIALS WE SPOKE WITH WON'T
SHARE ALL OF THE SECURITY
PROTOCOL WITH US.
THEY DON'T WANT POTENTIAL
INTRUDERS TO KNOW ABOUT THEM.
BUT MOST SCHOOLS HAVE ONE
COMMON POLICY.
>> WE HAVE A SINGLE POINT OF
ENTRANCE TO SCHOOLS WE
ENCOURAGE SCHOOLS TO FOLLOW
THAT PROTOCOL.
SO VISITORS ARE CHECKING IN IN
ONE PLACE IN THE SCHOOL.
>> THIS DRILL HELD FOUR YEARS
AGO AT ST. IG NAISHUS.
>> I HOOL, -- HIGH SCHOOL.
NOW, THEY HOLD TWO DRILLS A
YEAR.
SCHOOLg#:]ç RESOURCE OFFICERS HE
TAUGHT STUDENTS SOME BASICS,
MAY KEEP THEM ALIVE IN AN
INVIEWED TROOUDER GETS ON
CAMPUS.
>> RUN, HIDE, AND THEN, FIGHT.
IF YOU NEED BE.
WHICH WE NEVER WANT TO HAPPEN.
BUT RUN, HIDE AND FIGHT.
>> THE PRINCIPAL SAYS THEY'RE
MORE AWARE OF THE SECURITY
HOLDS.
>> RECOGNIZING WE HAVE
MULTIPLE ACCESS POINTS IN
SCHOOLS, BUT WE HAVE TRIED TO
ICE YOL YAIT THOSE.
SO-ISOLATE THOSE TO SO WE'RE
AWARE.
>> IN COLUMBINE, OFFICERS
WAITED FOR S.W.A.T. TEAMS TO
ASSEMBLE BEFORE GOING N WHILE
THAT HAPPENED, THE SHOOTER
KILLED MORE STUDENTS, NOW,
POLICE CHANGED TACTICS.
>> IF THERE IS A VIOLENT
INCIDENTS ONGOING, ACTIVE
SHOOTER WE MAKE IMMEDIATE
ACTION.
WE KNOW THAT LIVES ARE AT
STAKE.
IF THERE IS IMMEDIACY, OUR
8Ht:Sb TO GATHER
AND ENGAGE.
>> AS SCHOOLS CHIEF SAYS,
SINGLE MOST EFFECTIVE SECURITY
MEASURE OF ALL IS AWARENESS
THAT, IS WHAT THEY TELL
STUDENTS.
IF YOU NOTICE SOMETHING, TELL
AN ADULT.
CALL 911.
THANK YOU.
>> SCHOOLS AROUND THE BAY
TRYING TO HELP STUDENTS AND
STAFF DEAL WITH THIS TRAGEDY N
UNION CITY, SCHOOL DISTRICT
OFFICIALS CONSOLED EACH OTHER.
ONE PSYCHOLOGIST FIGURING
OLDER KIDS WERE LIKELY TO
LEARN ABOUT THE CONNECTICUT
SHOOTING THROUGH SOCIAL MEDIA.
SHE ALSO HELPED TO CRAFT AN E
MAIL TO GO STAFF AND TEACHER
AS CROSS THE DISTRICT.
>> LOOK FOR IN STUDENTS THAT
MIGHT, THIS MIGHT HAVE A BIG
IMPACT ON WH. TO REFER THEM
FOR SERVICES.
>> IN OAKLAND, ADMINISTRATORS
SAY THEY'RE TRYING TO GIVE OUT
INFORMATION WITHOUT DRAMA
TIESING IT AND TRYING TO
REASSURE STUDENTS THEY HAVE
MANY PEOPLE LOOKING OUT FOR
THEM.
>> SO, ONCE AGAIN AIR,
SHOOTING MASSACRE REKINDLING
LONG RUNNING DEBATE IN THIS
COUNTRY, BEING TALKED ABOUT
WITH RENEWED VIGOR IN
SACRAMENTO TONIGHT.
WE'RE LIVE WITH BOTH SIDES OF
THE ISSUE.
NANNETTE?
>> THE BRADY CAMPAIGN RANKS
CALIFORNIA AS HAVING THE
STRICTEST CONCONTROL LAWS IN
THE COUNTRY.
ADVOCATES ARE SEIZING ON THE
MOMENT, STATE SENATOR
CONSIDERING REINTRO DUGS A
BILL.
GOVERNOR BROWN ORDERED FLAGS
AT THE CALIFORNIA STATE
CAPITOL TO BE FLOWN AT HALF
STAFF CALLING THE TRAGEDY A
HEART BREAKING LOSS.
23 YEARS AGO CALIFORNIA HAD A
SCOOT SKOOL SHOOTING IN
STOCKTON.
FIVED KIDS LEFT DEAD.
THAT SPARK]Af AID MOVE NMT
CALIFORNIA THAT RESULTED IN
THE STRONGEST GUN LAWS IN THE
COUNTRY.
>> I THINK IT HIT HOME THE
IMANCE OF STRENGTHENING OUR
LAWS AND SPURRED ACTION.
>> THE BRADY CAMPAIGN CREDITS
CALIFORNIA STRONG GUN LAWS FOR
MAKING IT SAFER ON STREETS.
>> CALIFORNIA HAS LOWEST
MORTALITY RATE FROM FIREARM
DEATH IN THE NATION.
>> THE CONNECTICUT SHOOTING IS
PROMPTING CALLS FOR STRICTER
GUN LAW AS CROSS THE COUNTRY,
EVEN IN CALIFORNIA.
MOST RECENT POLLS SHOW
AMERICANS IN GENERAL
SAVOR -- FAVOR MORE
RESTRICTIONS.
>> WE DON'T NEED STRICTER GUN
GUN TROLL.
>> THIS GUN STORE OWNER SAYS
LAWS ARE WORKING FINE.
>> ISOLATED INCIDENTS, IT'S
TRAGIC BUT YOU KNOW, WE CAN'T
GOING TO SOLVE THE
PROBLEM.
IT'S NOT F PEOPLE ARE WANTING
TO"Dl DO SOMETHING BAD, THEY'RE
GOING TO FIGURE OUT A WAY TO
DO IT.
>> THE MICHIGAN HOUSE APPROVED
A CONCEALED WEAPONS LAW
ALLOWING TRAIN PEMZ TO CARRY
GUNS IN SCHOOLS, STADIUMS AND
CHURCHES, AN IDEA HE SAYS
COULD HAVE BROUGHT DOWN THE
SHOOTER FASTER IF THE LAW WAS
IN PLACE THERE.
>> IF SOMEONE WERE TO HAVE A
GUN THERE, A CONCEALED WEAPON
AND KNEW HOW TO USE IT THE
SITUATION COULD HAVE NOT
GOTTEN AS FAR AS IT DID.
>> I DO NOT THINK THAT IS A
SOLUTION.
THAT I BROFSH BRINGING MORE
FIREARMS IS ONLY GOING TO
CREATE MORE BULLETS FLYING.
>> THE CONNECTICUT GUNMAN USED
A GLOCK AND SIG SEMI AUTOMATIC
HANDGUN.
LIVE IN SAN FRANCISCO, ABC 7
NEWS.
>> THANK YOU.
VIGILS SPRINGING UP OVER THE
COUNTRY IN WASHINGTON, D.C. IN
FRONT OF THE WHITE HOUSE A
GROUP CALLED FOR STRONGER GUN
FIREARMS.
THIS BECAME A CANDLE LIGHT
VIGIL.
MORE PEOPLE JOINED THE GROUP Z
HERE IS A PICTURE OF A VIGIL
IN SAN4/+dñ JOSE.
THE MOTHER OF 6-YEAR-OLD
DIAVIANO CAVATO SHOWED THIS
NOTEO, LIGHTING A CANDLE FOR
CHILDREN.
THE SIGN READS SAN JOSE LOVES
SHES, CONNECTICUT.
WE'RE GETTING WORD OF A VIGIL
TO BE HELD IN OAKLAND TONIGHT.
AT BROADWAY AND 14th STREET
FROM 6:00 TO 8:00 P.M.
FOR VICTIMS OF GUN VIOLENCE.
>> IT SEEMS TO HAPPEN OFTEN
THESE DAYS.
JUST THIS YEAR, ONE OF THE
DEADLIEST SHOOTINGS IN
CALIFORNIA HISTORY HAPPEN NTD
BAY AREA.
SEVEN PEOPLE KILLED IN OIKOS
UNIVERSITY.
THE GUNMAN IS UNDERGOING
EVALUATION.
IN FEBRUARY, THREE STUDENTS
KILLED AND TWO WOUNDED AS
STUDENTS WAITED FOR BUSES TO
OTHER SCHOOLS.
THE DEADLIEST SCHOOL SHOOTING
HAPPENED IN 2007 IN VIRGINIA
TECH.
THE GUNMAN KILLED 32 PEOPLE,
THEN SHOT AND KILLED HIMSELF
IN 1999 IN COLUMBINE HIGH
SCHOOL TWO, STUDENTS KILLED 12
CLASSMATES AND A TEACHER
BEFORE THEMSELVES IN THE
SCHOOL LIBRARY.
26 OTHERS WERE WOUNDED.
>> AS THIS TRAGEDY UNFOLDS
STAY WITH US FOR CONTINUING
COVERAGE.
YOU CAN RECEIVE URGENT UPDATES
ON YOUR SMART PHONE BY DOWN
LOADING OUR FREE NEWS APP AND
OPTING FOR PUSH NOTE FICKS.
YOU CAN SIGN UP ON ABC 7
NEWS.COM.
PAGE AND ON TWITTER ON ABC 7
TO MONITOR THIS TRAGEDY FOR
AND WORLD NEWS WITH DIANE
SAWYER WILL AIR A SPECIAL
BROADCAST ON THE TRAGEDY
TONIGHT BEGINNING RIGHT AFTER
THIS NEWSCAST AT 5:30.
>> MOVING ON TO OTHER NEWS,
UPDATE ON BREAKING NEWS ON THE
PENINSULA.
POLICE SAY THE DRIVER OF THE
BLACK VOLKSWAGON CRASHING INTO
ANOTHER VEHICLE ON NORTHBOUND
I-280 HAS BEEN ARRESTED AND
WILL BE CHARGED WITH VEHICULAR
MANSLAUGHTER.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT LIVE
PICTURES OF THE SCENE.
JUST A HORRIFIC CRASH.
THREE PEOPLE WERE KILLED.
VICTIMS CHANGING A TIRE IN THE
THAT VEHICLES SWAG ON.
YOU CAN SEU@[#ñ RESULTING TRAFFC
BACK UP ON 280 AS A RESULT OF
THE CRASH.
>> STUDENTS BACK IN CLASS IN
CUPPER TINO FOLLOWING SPRAY
PAINTED BOMB THREATS THAT
CLOSED TWO TWO SKOOLZ
YESTERDAY.
THIS GRAFFITI IN IS A SAN JOSE
NAMED A TEACHER FROM MONTE
VISTA HIGH.
STUDENTS WERE RELIEVED BY THE
POLICE ON CAMPUS TODAY.
>> FEEL COMFORT YACHBLT I KNOW
THERE IS NOT A BOMB HERE, I'M
PRETTY SURE THAT THE POLICE
HAVE A GOOD HANDLE ON IT.
>> THE SHERIFF OFFICE HAS
ADDITIONAL DEPUTIES ON THE
CAMPUS AND HAS A COUPLE
OFFICERS AT THE HOME OF THE
TEACHER MENTIONED IN THIS
THREAT.
>> THERE WAS MORE FLOODING AT
THE INTERCHANGE OF HIGHWAYS 1
AND 101 THIS MORNING.
MOTOR YIFRS HAD TO NAVIGATE AS
THEY CAME OFF HIGHWAY 101.
WATER LAPPED OVER THE ROAD.
THIS WEEK'S SHORE LINE
EXPERIENCED SOME OF THE
HIGHEST SHORE LINES OF THE
YEAR, AT SEVEN FEET.
FLOODING CROSSED PART OF THE
PCH IN SUNSET BEACH IN
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA.
>> AND KING TIDE HAS COME AND
GONE, MORE RAIN IS ON THE WAY.
SANDHYA PATEL IS HERE WITH A
LOOK AT WHAT IS IN STORE.
>> YES.
WE'LL HAVE RAIN FOR WEEKEND.
WE HAVE SOME VERY LIGHT RAIN
AROUND THE REGION.
I AM GOING TO SHOW YOU WHERE
IT'S RAINING NOW.
WE TAKE YOU FIRST TO FREMONT
AREA, BLACK HALL ROAD, SOME
VERY LIGHT RAIN.
WE HEAD DOWN TOWARDS MILPITAS
AREA, ALLEN ROTH, -- ROCK.
MODERATE RAIN SHOWING UP Z I'M
GETTING CONFIRMATION FROM THE
RAIN ON PEOPLE ON TWITTER.
ONE SAID HAD A RAINY DRIVE
HOME.
AND GREAT ADVICE.
OF COURSE, OUR OWN RADAR WILL
BE WATCHING ANOTHER SYSTEM DUE
Ñ
I'LL LET YOU KNOW WHICH ONE OF
THE TWO DAYS WILL BE THE DRIER
FOR PLAN AUTOS THANK YOU.
>> STILL TO COME HERE TONIGHT
A HARSH SENTENCE FOR A RAPIST
TERRORIZING IN THE MISSION
DISTRICT.
AUTHORITIES SAY CHANCES ARE
SLIM TO NONE HE GETS OUT ON
PAROLE.
>> STUDENTS WRITE LET DWRORZ
SANTA NOT FOR WHEN THEY WANT,
INSTEAD, THESE TO HELP MAKE
WISHES COME TRUE FOR SICK
CHILDREN.
TH
>>> A FORMER WORKER WILL SPEND
HIS LIFE WITHOUT -- BEHIND
BARS.
HE WAS SENTENCED TO 373 YEARS
TO LIFE UNDERSTOOD TO PAY OVER
$250,000 IN RESTITUTION TO THE
VICTIMS.
THE JUDGE SAID HE SHOW NOD
REMORSE FOR THE RAPES TAKING
PLACE IN THE MISSION DISTRICT
BETWEEN JUNE AND DECEMBER OF
LAST YEAR.
THE FAMILY STORMED OUT OF THE
COURTROOM AFTER THE SENTENCE
WAS READ.
ONE OF THE VICTIMS TALKED
ABOUT THE CRIME STATING THAT
THE ASSAULT DRAINED THE LIFE
OUT OF HER BODY. A JUDGE IN
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA IS BEING
TAKEN TO TASK FOR SAIS SAIING
A RAPE VICTIM DIDN'T PUT UP A
VIT WHEN ASSAULTED.
THE JUDGE TOOK THE VIEW THAT
IF SOMEONE DOESN'T WANT TO
HAVE SEX, THE BODY WILLQVs,L NOT
PERMIT THAT TO HAPPEN.
THE CALIFORNIA COMMISSION ON
JUDICIAL PERFORMANCE VOTED TO
PUBLICLY ADMONISH THE JUDGE
AND SAID COMMENTS WERE
INSKPRORPT A BREECH OF
JUDICIAL ETHIC AUTOS THE
CONCORD TEENAGER WHO ADMITTED
KILLING A FATHER AND DAUGHTER
HIS SPEEDING SUV BACK IN COURT
FR A HEARING TODAY.
DAVID ROSEN NOW 18 YEARS OLD
WILL HAVE TO PAY FOR LOSSES
RESULTING FROM THE DEATHS OF
THE 9-YEAR-OLD ASK HER FATHER.
THEY INCLUDE FUNERAL EXPENSES
AND LOST WAGES.
THE TWO RIDING BIKES LAST
APRIL WHEN HIT BY ROSEN,
EXPECTED IN COURT FOR A FINAL
DECISION IN TERMS OF
RESTITUTION FEBRUARY 20th.
>> DEPARTMENTS AND POLICE
DEPARTMENTS RELEASED A
SURVEILLANCE VIDEO SCREEN SHOT
OF A SUSPECT WANT FORWARD A
CRIME SPREE TARGETING FOUR
DRUG STORES IN 36 HOURS,
STARTING ON WEDNESDAY IN
DUBLIN.
THE A LOT OF ONE WAS YESTERDAY
AFTERNOON, AT THE DUBLIN
SAFEWAY PHARMACY.
AND IN ALL, FOUR ROBBERIES, HE
GAVE A CLERK A NET SAYING HE
WAS ARMED AND WANTED DRUGS
LIKE OXYCONTIN.
>> WHAT HAPPENED TODAY IN
CONNECTICUT SADDENED ALL OF US
AND WE WANT TO SHARE A STORY
NOW OF HOPE AND LOVE.
HUNDREDS WROTE QLERTS ASKING
HIM TO GRNT A WISH TO SICK
KIDS.
THAT IS PART OF A MAKE A WISH
CAMPAIGN.
>> HOW MANY LETTERS DID OUR
SECOND GRADERS HEAR?
>> THESE OF ARE A FEW OF KIDS
IN FREMONT WHO WROTE A WISH.
>> I WISHED ABOUT MY FAMILY.
AND FRIENDS.
>> MY MOM AND DAD HAVE A GREAT
ND NOT
HAVE TO STRUGGLE WITNESS.
>> FOR ALL CHILDREN SAY STAY
OUT OF THE HOSPITAL, FEEL
BETTER ABOUT THEMSELVES.
>> THEIR SECOND GRADE TEACHER
ORGANIZED THIS PROJECT.
>> THIS COULD WITH SOME OF THE
KIDS WONDER WHEN THEY WISH
FOR.
>> MACY'S DONATED $2 TO MAKE A
WISH FOUNDATION, GRANTING
WISHES TO KIDS WITH LIFE
THREATENING MEDICAL
CONDITIONS.
SHE HAD A SHOPPING SPREE TODAY,
BEFORE FLYING IN JANUARY TO
MEET JUSTIN BEIBER.
STUDENTS AND PARENTS MANAGED
TO WRITE 41,000 LETTER AUTOS
WHEN I DO IT, MY HANDS HURT.
BUT I KEEP ON DOING IT.
BECAUSE I WANT KIDS TO GET OUT
OF THE HOSPITAL.
>> THE MAKE A WISH FOUNDATION
WILL NOW RECEIVE MORE THAN
$80,000 WHICH WILL BE SPENT ON
GRANTING WISHES TO ABOUT EIGHT
SICK CHILDREN.
>> IF YOU'RE SICK AND IN PAIN.
YOU DON'T LIKE TO HAVE MUCH TO
DO.
YOU CAN'T GO OUT, ANYWHERE.
PAY IT FORWARD, TO THINK OF
OTHERS FIRST.
AND PLUS WE'RE GETTING THEM TO
RIGHT.
>> HE TOLD US HIS BABY SISTER
HAD BEEN SICK.
>> I HOPE SHE GETS BETTER.
>> IS BETTER NOW.
>> THE POWER OF BELIEVING.
INOc1I FREMONT ABC 7 NEWS.
>> WHAT BEAUTIFUL FACES.
WHAT A BEAUTIFUL THING TO DO.
>> ABSOLUTELY OO. SANDHYA
PATEL IS HERE.
AND OUR RADAR WILL BE WATCHING
RAIN THIS WEEKEND.
SO DON'T PANIC OR CANCEL YOUR
PLANS.
IT'S NOT LOOKING THAT BAD.
WE'RE LOOKING ACROSS THE BAY
THERE.
AND WE HAVE A FEW SHOWERS OUT
THEY'RE DECREASING IN
COVERAGE.
HERE IS WHAT IT'S RAINING
RIGHT NOW.
IT'S MOSTLY AROUND EAST BAY TO
SOUTH BAY.
SANTA CRUZ MOUNTAINS THEY'RE
GETTING RAINFALL.
SOUTH BAY AS WE HEAD TOWARDS
SOUTH KING ROAD AND HIGHWAY
101.
ALLEN ROCK.
TOWARDS THE EAST BAY, YOU'LL
NOTICE CHERRY STREET, FREMONT
BOULEVARD, LIGHT RAIN.
SPRINKLES OR LIT RAIN IS ALL
WE'RE EXPECTING.
IT'S SNOWING IN THE SIERRA
NEVADA.
SO IF YOU HAVE PLANS TO GO
THERE, MORE SNOW IS INM- THEJuia
FORECAST.
NOW TEMPERATURES ARE CALLING
AND IT'S BEEN A CHILLY
AFTERNOON.
MOST AREAS INTO UPPER 40S TO
50S THIS AFTERNOON.
NUMBERS INTO UPPER 40s ALONG
COAST WE HAVE LOW 50s AROUND
THE COAST AND BAY.
SO CHILLY CONDITIONS AND
SHOWERS EARLY IN THE MORNING
ON SUNDAY HERE, IS A LOOK AT
SATELLITE AND RADAR.
THIS IS A SYSTEM BRINGING US
RAIN NOW.
WE'RE WATCHING ANOTHER SYSTEM
THAT WILL PRODUCE RAIN FOR
SATURDAY.
LET'S CHECK OUT OUR COMPUTER
ANIMATION, 8:00 IN THE MORNING
YOU'RE FINE.
RAIN STARTS TO APPEAR NEAR THE
GOLDEN GATE BRIDGE.
IT WILL SPREAD FOR AFTERNOON.
IT'S A LIGHT TO MODERATE RAIN
EVENT AND WILL BE CHILLY
POSSIBILITY OF ZMO COULD SEE A
FEW FLURRIES OVER MOUNT
HAMILTON.
SHOWERS LINGERING INTO SUNDAY
MORNING.
YOUR EARLY MANS MAYBE INTO
AFTERNOON UP INTO THE NORTH
BAY.
BUT THEN, WE'RE DONE.
WITH THE RAIN.
UNTIL MONDAY.
ALL RIGHT.
RAINFALL TOTALS LOOKING LIKE
THIS.
HIGHEST INTO THE MOUNTAINS.
SANTA CRUZ MOUNTAINS UP TO A
QUARTER INCH.
REST OF THE BAY AREA UP UNTIL
AT LIGHTER RAINFALL.
TOMORROW MORNING CLOUDS PART
WAYS WE'LL START OUT PARTLY
CLOUDY SKIES AND NOT AS COLD
AS THIS MORNING.
TOMORROW MORNING 34 SANTA
ROSEA, NAPA.
36 DEGREES CONCORD, LOOK AT
THAT.
LIVERMORE JUST ABOUT FREEZING.
36 DEGREES.
40 DEGREES IN HALF MOON BAY
SO. MAKE SURE YOU BUNDLE UP
OUT OF THE DOOR.
KEEP PLAYERS AROUND.
IT'S GOING TO BE CHILLY.
LOW 50s TOWARDS THE SOUTH BAY,
TEMPERATURES UPPER 40S TO LOW
50s.
ACCU-WEATHER FORECAST, AFTER
EARLY SHOURKS SUNDAY, YOU'RE
FINE THE REST OF THE DAY.
MONDAY, RAIN IS LIKELY HEADING
INTO EARLY TUESDAY, BREAK ON
WEDNESDAY.
THURSDAY, DOESN'T LOOK THAT
PROMISING.
AS FAR AS RAIN BUT CHANCE OF
Y÷, LATE FRIDAY, IN
THE ACCU-WEATHER FORECAST.
>> THANK YOU.
>> STILL TO COME, AN UPROAR OF
>>> NOW BACK TO THE LATEST ON
THE TRAGIC SHOOTING MORE ABOUT
ADAM LANZA, THE 20-YEAR-OLD
BEHIND THE DEADLY SHOOTING
KILLING 26 PEOPLE INCLUDING 20
CHILDREN.
HE OPENED FIRE IN AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
HE TURNED THE GUN ON HIMSELF.
POLICE SAY HE ALSO KILLED HIS
MOTHER, NANCY LANZA INSIDE OF
HER HOME BEFORE GOING TO
SCHOOL.
THE GUNMAN'S BROTHER, RYAN
TAKEN INTO CUSTODY AND
QUESTIONED.
HE IS NOT A SUSPECT IN THIS
SHOOTING.
AUTHORITIES SAY HE IS
COOPERATING FULLY.
PLEASE STAY WITH US AND ABC 7
NEWS.COM FOR CONTINUING
UPDATES ON THIS TRAGIC,
BREAKING NEWS STORY.
UNFOLDING AND WILL BE FOR
HOURS, YOU CAN RECEIVE URGENT
UPDATES DOWN LOADING OUR FREE
ABC 7 NEWS APP OPTING FOR PUSH
NOTIFICATIONS.
I USE IT, IT'S HANDY. THE TEAM
IS SENDING UPDATES ON THE
SCHOOL TRAGEDY AS THEY
DEVELOP.
YOU CAN SIGN UP FOR BREAKING
NEWS LETTER ON ABC 7 NEWS.COM.
WE'LL CONTINUE TO KEEP YOU
INFORMED IN THAT MAT YEAR
BREAKING NEWS IN THE SOUTH
BAY.
SKY 7 HD IS LIVE AT THE GREAT
MALL IN MILPITAS, POLICE
EVACUATED A KHOL'S STORE THERE
BECAUSE OF A MESSAGE ABOUT A
BOMB WRILTEN ON THE WALL OF
THE MEN'S REST ROOM.
POLICE VOWED NO EVIDENCE OF A
BOMB BUT CLEARED STORES TO
MAKE SURE AREAS ARE SAFE.
POLICE HOPE TO REOPEN THIS
AREA BY ABOUT 8:00 WE'LL LET
YOU KNOW IF ANYTHING CHANGES.
>> LET'S TRANSITION TO OTHER
THINGS FOR JUST A MOMENT.
IT'S IN WITH OLD IN A CLASSIC
CAP ROOM.
GOLD DUST LOUNGE AND OTHER
MEMORABILIA THIS MORNING FROM
OLD LOCATIONS NEAR UNION
SQUARE INTO NEW SPOTS.
IT'S STILL BEINGOYP/I)ENOVATED
AHEAD OF THE SCHEDULED
OPENING.
MORE ON THAT IN JUST A MOMENT.
>> THIS SF A PERFECT PLACE FOR
GOLD DUST.
AND WE HAVE A PERFECT FIT TO
PUT GOLD DUST INTO THE MIDDLE
OF IT.
>> WHEN THE NEW GOLD DUST
LOUNGE OPENS FRIDAY, JANUARY
11th WILL ROLL BACK THE PRICE
OF IRISH COFFEE TO 25 CENTS
FOR THE WEEKEND.
WHAT IT COST IN
>>> PLEASE STAY RIGHT HERE, A
SPECIAL ONE OUR EDITION IS
NEXT.
RIGHT AFTER THAT, WE'LL BE
BACK WITH A HALF OUR EDITION
OF ABC 7 NEWS AT 6:30 WITH
LOCAL IMPACT OF THE TRAGIC
EVENT.
>> AND UC BERKELEY THIS
MORNING ANNOUNCED IT'S
DECISION TO SHELF IT'S
CONTROVERSIAL NEW LOGO
FEATURING A SMALL P IN A SMALL
U.
MOST CRITICS WANT TO GO TOóDZñ T
>>> THIS IS A SPECIAL ONE-HOUR
EDITION OF "WORLD NEWS," TRAGEDY
AT THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT WHERE TODAY
A NIGHTMARE UNFOLDED.
A GUNMAN KILLING 20 SMALL
CHILDREN, TEACHERS SCRAMBLING TO
SAVE THEM.
THE SHOOTER, 20 YEARS OLD, ALSO
AMONGED DEAD.
HIS MOTHER.
WE ARE HERE WITH TEACHERS, THE
STUDENTS WHO MADE IT OUT, AND
THE PARENTS WHO TELL US ABOUT
THE MOMENT WHEN THEY LEARNED
THEIR CHILD HAD SURVIVED.
>> TEARS COME TO YOUR EYES
IMMEDIATELY WHEN YOU KNOW YOUR
CHILD IS OKAY.
>> INSIDE THE SCHOOL, STORIES OF