OUND MINE.
DETECTIVE KATE BECKETT.
BECKETT.
NIKKI HEAT?
THE CHARACTER
HE'S BASING ON YOU.
AND THANKS TO MY FRIENDSHIP
WITH THE MAYOR,
I GET TO BE ON HER CASE.
I WOULD BE HAPPY
TO LET YOU SPANK ME.
AND TOGETHER,
WE CATCH KILLERS.
WE MAKE A PRETTY GOOD TEAM,
YOU KNOW?
LIKE STARSKY AND HUTCH,
TURNER AND HOOCH.
YOU DO REMIND ME
A LITTLE OF HOOCH.
(Sloan's "Who Taught You
to Live Like That?" playing)
♪ SHE CAME THROUGH INSPECTIONS
♪ TOWARDS ME IN SECTIONS
♪ THE LIFE DISAPPEARED
FROM THE ROOM ♪
♪ SHE ASKED ME POLITELY
♪ MAY I PUT THIS LIGHTLY?
♪ THE DEATH THAT YOU THOUGHT
WAS EXHUMED ♪
AAH! OFF WITH YOUR HEADS!
(grunts)
OH!
(women screaming indistinctly)
♪ WHO TAUGHT YOU
TO LIVE LIKE THAT? ♪
AAH!
ULL MOONS
WHAT IS IT ABOUT FULL MOONS
THAT BRING OUT
ALL THE CRAZIES?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU TELL ME.
AAH! OH!
♪ WHO TAUGHT YOU
TO LIVE LIKE THAT? ♪
HEY, KARPOWSKI.
HOW'S IT GOING?
SAME OLD, SAME OLD.
YOU, BECKETT?
AH, CAN'T COMPLAIN.
GOOD.
AAH!
(laughs) COME ON. YOU GUYS
SHOULD REALLY SELL TICKETS.
I MEAN, YOU GOT EVERYTHING--
MADNESS, MAYHEM.
NOW ALL YOU NEED IS--
(telephone rings)
♪ WHO TAUGHT YOU TO LIVE
LIKE THAT? ♪
BECKETT.
(camera shutter clicks,
police radio chatter)
ASHLEY COSWAY, 32,
COUPLES THERAPIST.
HUSBAND FOUND HER
JUST BEFORE MIDNIGHT.
(Esposito) HE WAS
PICKING HER UP ON HIS WAY HOME
AFTER THE ST. JOHN'S GAME
AT THE GARDEN.
ANY WITNESSES?
NONE SO FAR,
BUT I DID FIND A RECEIPT
FOR THIS TAKEOUT RIGHT HERE.
HMM. DINNER FOR TWO.
YEAH, IT'S FROM SZECHUAN WOK
OVER ON 9th.
HUSBAND RECOGNIZE
THE NUMBER?
RECEIPT DOESN'T MATCH ANY OF
THE CARDS IN  MNH-MNH. WALLET.NE
WHEN WAS IT CHARGED?
6:02 P.M.
LANIE PUTS THE TIME OF DEATH
AROUND 8:00.
WELL, WHOEVER
SHE HAD DINNER WITH
MAY HAVE BEEN THE LAST PERSON
TO SEE HER AL
OR THE FIRST ONE TO
SEE HER DEAD. RUN THE CARD.
YOU KNOW, IF THIS WAS
ONE OF THOSE SUPER SCIENCE-Y
FORENSIC SHOWS,THOSE SU-
THEY'D STICK SOME ELECTRODES
IN THESE FISHES' BRAINS,
GET A FISH-EYE VIEW
OF WHATEVER THEY SAW.
(camera shutter clicks)
(Lanie) BECKETT.
DR. PARISH, WHEN'D THEY CHANGE
THE DRESS CODE DOWNTOWN?
WELL, UNLIKE YOU, I DON'T
SIT AROUND WORK ALL NIGHT
WAITING FOR THE NEXT VIC
TO SHOW.
QUIT LOOKING AT THE GIRLS,
CASTLE.
ROGER THAT.
MULTIPLE G.S.W.s. ENTRIES
LOOK FAIRLY SMALL CALIBER.
PROBABLY A .22.
"PSYCHO THE RAPIST,
YOUR OUT OF TIME"?
IT LOOKS LIKE A PATIENT
LOSALSO HIS COMMAND OF GRAMMAR.
"YOUR" SHOULD BE
YOU'R-E, AS IN "YOU ARE."
THAT'S NOT EVEN
A TOUGH ONE,
NOT LIKE WHEN TO USE
"WHO" OR "WHOM"?
DO YOU REALLY THITHAT'S
THE TAKEAWAY HERE, CASTLE?
I'M JUST SAYING,
WHOEVER KILLED HER
ALSO MURDERED
THE ENGLISH LANGUAGE.
ANY SIGNS OF STRUGGLE?
BRUISES ON BOTH ARMS.
CHECK FOR FIBERS AND HAIR.
SEE
SEE IF OUR KILLER
LEFT ANYTHING BEHIND.
OKAY.
(police radio chatter)
CASTLE.
MM-HMM.
(man) UH, NO. SHE, UH, SHE NEVER
DISCUSSED HER PATIENTS.
ASH WAS, UH, WAS
VERY PROFESSIONAL THAT WAY.
WHAT WAS SHE DOING HERE
SO LATE?HE ALWAYS WOULD E
UH, SHE ALWAYS WOULD HAVE
A COUPLE NIGHTS A MONTH
WHERE SHE'D WORK LATE
WRITING UP CASE NOTES.
I'D USE THAT AS A TIME
TO GO OUT WITH THE BOYS
AND
AND WHEN I'D GET BACK,
I'D WALK HER HOME.
DID YOU KNOW WHO
SHE WAS HAVING DINNER WITH?
NO. I MEAN, UNLESS SOMEONE
CALLED HER AFTER WE SPOKE.
WHEN WAS THAT?
IT WAS BEFORE I LEFT WORK.
6:00-ISH.
I WAS, UH, I WAS
HEADING OUT TO THE GAME.
WHAT DID YOU T
JUST A MEANINGLESS CHECK-IN.
AND I...
(whistles)
RIGHT NOW I REMEMBER
I DIDN'T SAY "I LOVE YOU."
(camera shutter clicks)
THANK YOU, M(voice breaks) YEAH.
(Esposito) WE GO
(Esposit
POP AND DROP
ON 102nd.
FULL MOON STRIKES AGAIN.
ALL RIGHT, YOU GUYS
GO ON UPTOWN,
AND I'LL FINISH UP HERE.
SO MUCH FOR MY FAMOUS
WARM HONEY MILK
WITH JENNY TONIGHT.
DID I SAY THAT OUT LOUD?
YEAH.
HER HUSBAND CALLS
BEFORE 6:00,
AND THE FOOD'S PICKED UP
AT 6:02.
SHE KNEW WHO SHE WAS
HAVING DINNER WITH.
AMMAR.
HMM.
(Esposito) HEY, UH,
A WARM MILK NIGHTCAP
WITH YOUR LADY?
THAT IS SAD, BRO.
IT HELPS HER SLEEP.
OF YOUR VOICE?
HOW YOU DOING,     IT DOESN'T...
DR. PERLMUTTER?    WORKS ON ME.?
SHH.
THE BODY IS SPEAKING.
WHAT'S IT SAYING?
ONE TO THE MIDSECTION.
.38, MAYBE EVEN A .45.N..38E
HE WAS SHOT AT CLOSE RANGE
AND FROM BEHIND.
THAT'S COLD.
YEAH, WELL,
THAT'S THE LIVING FOR YOU.
HE HAVE ANY I.D.?
NO, WALLET'S GONE.
NO WATCH, NO JEWELRY.
MAYBE A MUGGING
GONE BAD.
A LOOKY LOO SAID
SHE RECOGNIZED HIMOOD.FRO.
GAVE HIS INFO TO
OFFICER WHOJAMIFACE OVER THERE.
WHOJAMIFACE?
NICE TO SEE YOU
MAKING AN EFFORT TO BOND
WITH THE RANK AND FILE,
PERLMUTTER.
(Castle) IT'S NOT LIKE YOU'RE
JUST LEAVING YOURSELF A NOTE,
YOU KNOW, TO BUY BREAD
ON THE WAY HOME.
(exhales deeply)
YOU'RE WRITING ON A PERSON
YOU JUST MURDERED.
YOU'RE TRYING TO MAKE A POINT--
A POINT YOU CARE
A GREAT DEAL ABOUT PRESUMABLY,
BECAUSE YOU JUST KILLED SOMEONE
TO MAKE IT.
SO HOW DO YOU NOT MAKE SURE
THAT YOU'RE USING
THE PROPER LANGUAGE
TO MAKE THAT POINT?
FRANK ANDERSON, RETIRED
MIDDLE SCHOOL MATH TEACHER
FROM I.S. 161.
YOU WANT IN?
UH, NO, THANKS.
FULL UP.
(cell phone beeps)
SO...
HOW'D YOU FIND THE BODY?
ON THE GROUND.
WAS HE POSITIONED
IN A CREEPY WAY?
YEAH, LIKE A GUY
WHO WAS SHOT.
OH.
SO JUST YOUR GARDEN-VARIETY
HOMICIDE/ROBBERY, HUH?
ACTUALLY...
POP AND DROPS ARE SOME OF
THE HARDEST CASES TO CLOSE.
RANDOMNESS OF THE VICTIM,
ANONYMOUS NATURE OF THE CRIME--
IT TAKES SOME REAL SERIOUS
DETECTIVE WORK.
OKAY. WELL, IF YOU GUYS
WANT ANY HELP,
YOU KNOW WHERE TO FIND ME.
HELP?
D   CASTLE.T SAY "HELP"?TLE.,
WE'LL PROBABLY CLOSE OURS
BEFORE YOUR THERAPIST.
REALLY?
MM-HMM.
WELL, PERHAPS YOU'D LIKE
TO MAKE THINGS INTERESTING.
WHOA. WAIT.
ARE YO
ARE YOU SAYING
YOU WANT TO WAGER
ON WHO SOLVES
THEIR CASE FIRST?THAT'S C
THAT'S SICK, BRO.
50 BUCKS?
WE WIN, YOU PAY US BOTH.
DEAL.
(Ryan and Esposito mutter)
(lowered voice) NOT A WORD
TO BECKETT, OKAY?
SHE FINDS OUT ABOUT THIS,
SHE'LL SHOOT US.
SECRETS, MURDER
AND GAMBLING--
THREE OF
MY FAVORITE PASTIMES.
MAY THE BEST MAN WIN.
(spits)
RICHARD, THAT'S APPALLING--
WAGERING ON DEATH.
THEY'RE ALREADY DEAD,
MOTHER.
AND WHO'S TO SAY THAT
CATCHING KILLERS CANNOT BE FUN?
HEY, DAD,
ARE YOU WORKING TONIGHT?
MAYBE. WHY?
OH, I JUST HAVE
MATH CLUB TILL 6:00,
AND THEN I WANTED
TO TAKE OWEN OUT
FOR A BIRTHDAY BANANA SPLIT
AT SERENDIPITY.
I JUST WANTED
TO DO SOMETHING SPECIAL
BECAUSE THINGS HAVE BEEN
A LITTLE ROCKY WITH US LATELY.
NOTHING SMOOTHES ROCKY
LIKE ROCKY ROAD.
JUST REMEMBER, IT'S A SCHOOL
NIGHT. BE HOME BY MIDNIGHT.
DAD, I'LL BE HOME BY 9:00.
LOVE YOU.
YEAH, BYE, DARLING.
LOVE YOU. BYE, GUYS.
AH, YOUNG LOVE--
FIRST BANANA SPLITS,
THEN SPLITTING ASSETS.
AH, MOTHER. YOU ARE
A HOPELESS ROMANTIC.
I KNOW.
(cell phone rings)
MM.
OOPS.
I'M OFF TO AN AUDITION.
AND I HAVE A BET TO WIN.
YES, DETECTIVE.
THAT'S MY CREDIT CARD.
I HAD DINNER WITH HER LAST
NIGHT. SHE'S MY BEST FRIEND.
WHEN I LEFT HER THERE,
SHE WAS ALIVE.
WHAT TIME DID YOU LEAVE,
MS. ROSSI?
AROUND 7:00.
THEN WHERE DID YOU GO?
TO DRINKS WITH OTHER
ASSOCIATES FROM MY FIRM.
I WAS AT THE GANSEVOORT BAR
UNTIL 11:00.
DID YOU MAKE PLANS
TO HAVE DINNER TOGETHER,
OR DID YOU JUST SHOW UP?
SHE CALLED ME.
SHE SAID SHE WANTED TO TALK.
BUT I-I DIDN'T--
I DIDN'T KNOW.
YOU DIDN'T KNOW WHAT?
I SHOULD HAVE
SAID SOMETHING.
I SHOULD'VE DONE SOMETHING,
YOU KNOW? I--
WHY DID SHE CALL, MS. ROSSI?
SHE NEEDED MY ADVICE
AS A LAWYER.
SOMETHING HAPPENED LAST FRIDAY,
SOMETHING BAD.
WHAT?
SHE WOULDN'T SAY, BUT I KNEW
IT WAS ONE OF HER PATIENTS.
SHE WANTED TO KNOW HOW TO GET
A RESTRAINING ORDER.
AGAINST WHO?
WHOM.
SHE WOULDN'T SAY.
GOD.
I SHOULD HAVE STAYED
WITH HER.
I SHOULDN'T HAVE LET HER
OFF THE HOOK.
(sighs)
LOOKS LIKE ASHLEY
TOOK HER OATH SERIOUSLY.
HER HUSBAND HAD NO IDEA
THAT SOMETHING BAD
HAPPENED ON FRIDAY.
DOCTOR/PATIENT PRIVILEGE
IS SUPPOSED TO PROTECT PEOPLE,
NOT GET THEM KILLED.
SO THE VIC'S GIRLFRIEND?
ALIBI IS GOOD.
COWORKERS CONFIRM THAT SHE
ARRIVED FOR DRINKS AT 7:15,
LEFT AT 11:00.
THE HUSBAND'S BUDDY
PLACES HIM AT THE GARDEN
FROM 7:00 TILL ABOUT 10:00.
WHICH LEAVES US
WITH FRIDAY'S PATIENTS.
I SURE WOULD LIKE A PEEK
AT DR. COSWAY'S NOTES.
NOT WITHOUT A WARRANT.
WE START BY RUNNING THE NAMES.
IF HE THREATENED
AND THEN KILLED HER,
HE'S PROBABLY GOT
VIOLENT PRIORS.
ONCE AGAIN, MR. AND MRS. MARX,
I'M VERY SORRY FOR YOUR LOSS.
THANK YOU.
(whistling)
AND A DARK CLOUD DESCENDS.
ANY HOT LEADS?
MATTER OF FACT, YES.
TURNS OUT OUR VICTIM WENT
FOR A WALK EVERY NIGHT.
AND GUESS WHO HANGS
IN THE PARK
RIGHT WHERE OUR VICTIM
WAS POPPED.
RECE   VERY RO POSTAL WORKERS.N.
NO, GANG KIDS.
VERY ROUGH GUYS.
DO THEY HANG OUT THERE
REGULARLY?
THAT'S RIGHT.
THEN THEY DIDN'T DO IT. IF
THEY'RE KNOWN TO HANG OUT THERE,
THEN THEY'RE GONNA KNOW
THEY'RE GONNA GET CAUGHT.
IF THEY'RE GONNA DO SOMETHING,
THEY'RE GONNA DO IT
SOMEWHERE ELSE.
I KNOW WHAT YOU'RE DOING,
CASTLE.
YOU'RE TRYING TO MESS
WITH OUR CONFIDENCE.
IF I WAS TRYING TO MESS
WITH YOUR CONFIDENCE,
I WOULD TELL YOU THAT OUR VICTIM
TALKED TO HER LAWYER FRIEND
ON THE NIGHT SHE WAS MURDERED
ABOUT A RESTRAINING ORDER.
AND DO YOU HAVE A SUSPECT?
WE'RE NARROWING IT DOWN.
BUT DOESN'T THAT HAVE
A LOVELY RING TO IT?
(singsongy)
RESTRAINING ORDER.
♪ RESTRAINING ORDER
(snaps fingers)
♪ ORDER
HEY.
I WAS JUST...
UM, THEY WERE...
THERE WAS TWO...
YEAH.
BECKETT, WE GOT A HIT.
HAL ROSS?
MULTIPLE ASSAULT CHARGES
OVER THE LAST TEN YEARS.
HE AND HIS WIFE WERE
DR. COSWAY'S 2:00 ON FRIDAY.
(elevator bell ding
(ding)
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
(Ryan) HEY. HEY, HEY!
HEY! HEY!
CASTLE, NOT COOL.
STAIRS.
(Esposito) GO, GO, GO.
WHY'D YOU DO THAT?
DO WHAT?
♪
Captioned by
Closed Captioning Services, Inc.
e.
g,
persistent ache.
My doctor diagnosed it
as fibromyalgia,
thought to be the
result of overactive nerves
that cause chronic
widespread pain.
Lyrica is believed
to calm these nerves.
I learned Lyrica can provide
significant relief
from fibromyalgia pain.
And for some people,
it can work in as early as
the first week of treatment.
So now I can do more of
the things that I enjoy.
Lyrica may cause serious
allergic reactions
or suicidal thoughts or actions.
Tell your doctor right away
if you have these,
new or worsening depression,
or unusual changes in mood
or behavior,
or any swelling or
affected breathing or skin,
or changes in eyesight,
including blurry vision
or muscle pain with fever
or tired feeling.
Common side effects
are dizziness, sleepiness,
weight gain, and swelling of
hands, legs and feet.
Don't drink alcohol
while taking Lyrica.
Don't drive or use machinery
until you know
how Lyrica affects you.
With less pain,
I'm feeling better
now that I've found Lyrica.
Ask your doctor
if Lyrica is right
for your fibromyalgia pain.
YOU SPEND ALL DAY COOKING IT.
SO WHY SPEND EVEN A MOMENT
CONSIDERING ANY BROTH
BUT SWANSON?
THE BROTH COOKS TRUST MOST
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
IN STUFFING AND MORE,
THE SECRET IS SWANSON.
[ Female Announcer ]
At Yoplait,
we want you to feel
even better
about your favorite flavors.
So when you call, tweet,
and post, we listen.
That's why Yoplait Light
and Yoplait Original
are now made with
no high fructose corn syrup.
And why we use
only natural colors
and natural flavors
in Yoplait Original.
So, anything else we can do
for you, let us know.
But you'll keep it
to yogurt, right?
'Cause we shouldn't really help
with your love life.
Yoplait. It is so good!
ALL RIGHT,
I'M JUST GONNA SAY IT--
I'VE GOT A FEELING.
DOESN'T HAPPEN OFTEN,
BUT I AM FEELIN' IT.
THIS IS OUR GUY.
(Beckett) MR. ROSS?
WHAT'S UP,
GARBAGE ON MY SIDEWALK AGAIN?
UH... WOULD YOU MIND
PUTTING THAT DOWN?
WHERE WERE YOU LAST NIGHT
BETWEEN THE HOURS OF...
WHEN WAS THAT AGAIN?
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
ARE YOU FAMILIAR
WITH ASHLEY COSWAY?
OH, YEAH, SURE. THE DOC.
WELL, SHE WAS MURDERED
LAST NIGHT.
WHAT? THE DOC'S DEAD?
CAN YOU CONFIRM
YOUR WHEREABOUTS
BETWEEN 7:30 AND 9:00
LAST NIGHT?
YEAH, SURE. I WAS HERE. I'M OPEN
TILL 10:00 EVERY NIGHT.
CAN ANYONE CORROBORATE THAT?
MY EMPLOYEES.
WELL, HOW CONVENIENT THAT
YOUR ALIBIS ARE ON YOUR PAYROLL.
WHAT WOULD MAKE YOU THINK
THAT I KILLED THE DOC?
MR. ROSS, YOU HAVE A HISTORY
OF VIOLENCE--ASSAULT, BATTERY.
OKAY, WELL, WHY DO YOU THINK
I WAS IN...
THERAPY.
OKAY, DOC COSWAY SHOWED ME
THAT I WAS
ONLY HURTING MYSELF.
COME ON. HAL, WE KNOW SOMETHING
BAD HAPPENED LAST FRIDAY.
(snaps fingers)
COME ON.
SOMETHING HAPPENED, ALL RIGHT,
BUT IT WASN'T IN MY SESSION.
UNH-UNH. YOU WANT TO TALK
TO SOMEBODY?
YOU TRY THE APPOINTMENT
BEFORE MINE.
WHY IS THAT?
JUDY AND I, WE ARE
IN THE LITTLE WAITING ROOM
BEFORE OUR SESSION.
WE HEAR ALL THIS YELLING.
ABOUT WHAT?
I DON'T KNOW, BUT THIS GUY WAS
CURSING DOC COSWAY OUT BIG-TIME.
AND IT WAS KINDA SCARY.
I WAS TEMPTED TO GO IN THERE,
BUT THEN WE HEARD
THE GUY LEAVE.
DID YOU GET A GOOD LOOK
AT HIS FACE?
NO, NO, NO. HE WENT OUT
THE HALLWAY DOOR. DOC GOT US.
SHE WAS RATTLED, BUT SHE DID
OUR SESSION ANYWAY.
I GOT A FEELING
THIS ISN'T OUR GUY.
(Beckett)
HINKLE. EVAN HINKLE.
HE'S HAD THE APPOINTMENT
BEFORE THE ROSSES
EVERY WEEK
FOR THE LAST TWO YEARS.
THE GUY IS CLEAN.
THERE'S NO RECORD OF ANYTHING.
TWO STRAIGHT YEARS
OF THERAPY--
MAYBE HE JUST SNAPPED.M IN.VE U.
I'M GONNA GO GET A COFFEE.
ESPOSITO TIPPED ME OFF
TO THE BET.
THOUGHT I'D TOSS
A LITTLE TOWARDS OURS.
TOSS AWAY, MY FRIEND.AD THE WORD
IF ANYONE ELSE
WANTS A TASTE.
(Ryan) LET'S GO.
COME ON, BIG FELLA.
COME ON.
TO THE LEFT, OVER HERE.
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA,AT,
LOOKING FOR A GANG MEMBER, WE
LIKE A TEENAGER.
YOU WERE RIGHT.
ALIBIED OUT.
SO WHO'S  TO BE WORKING IN TUGGD
TO BE WORKING IN THE SAME AREA
THE SAME NIGHT
OUR VIC WAS KILLED.
OH, YEAH. HE WAS PICKED UP
WITH A .45 ON HIM,
WHICH HAPPENS TO BE
THE SAME ROUND
THAT WAS FOUND IN OUR VIC.
JUST WAITING ON BALLISTICS,
UNLESHE HASN'T ASKED IRST.
SO WHERE'S HIS LAWYER?A.
THAT WAS FOOH, WHOA, WHOA.
HE HASN'T ASKED FOR ONE.
WELL, I KNOW A GUY.
OH, WHAT'S THE MATTER, CASTLE?
ARE YOU GETTING WORRIED?
WOR-WORRIED?
I'LL MAKE YOU CRY.
YOU WANT TO BET
OR MAYBE DOUBLE DOWN?
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO,
NOT MONEY. HUMILIATION.
HMM.
LOSER WEARS A DRESS
TO THE PRECINCT FOR A WEEK.
WHY STOP THERE?
LOSER ALSO SHAVES HIS HEAD.
OR ARE YOU CHICKEN?
(snaps fingers)
YOU'RE ON, HONEY MILK.
HONEY MILK.
DAMN IT.
FOR THE RECORD, MR. HINKLE,
YOU ARE ADMITTING
THAT YOU WERE
DR. COSWAY'S 1:00 APPOINTMENT?
I KNEW THIS WOULD HAPPEN.
I KNEW IT.
FIRST TIME I MET HER,
I KNEW SHE'D LEAVE ME.
WHY DOES THIS ALWAYS HAPPEN?
WHY DO PEOPLE KEEP LEAVING ME?
SHE DIDN'T LEAVE YOU,
MR. HINKLE.
SHE WAS MURDERED.
YEAH, JUST LIKE
MY FIRST WIFE.
YOUR FIRST WIFE
WAS MURDERED?
THAT'S RIGHT.
I SMOTHERED HER TO DEATH.
YEAH.
THAT'S WHAT SHE TOLD ME.
I MURDERED HER WITH LOVE.
THAT'S WHY SHE LEFT.
JUST TELL US ABOUT
YOUR LAST APPOINTMENT
WITH DR. COSWAY.
WE WERE JUST STARTING
TO MAKE PROGRESS.
YOU KNOW THE IRONY HERE?
HER DEATH IS MY MOMENT
OF GREATEST CRISIS,
AND I DON'T HAVE HER
TO LEAN ON. (chuckles)
WHAT WAS
ALL THE SCREAMING ABOUT
AT THE APPOINTMENT
LAST FRIDAY?
SCREAM--LAST FRIDAY? I D--
I DID NOT SEE HER LAST FRIDAY.
YOU'RE IN THE BOOKS.
YOU'RE, WITH AN APOSTROPHE.
YEAH, WELL, I CANCELED
AN HOUR BEFORE.
YOU CANCELED?
YES. YES, I WAS HAVING
CHEST PAINS.
I WENT TO THE E.R.
AT ST. VINCENT'S.
$15,000 LATER, IT TURNS OUT
I WAS JUST HAVING
A PANIC ATTACK ABOUT MOTHER.
YOU KNOW...
(exhales deeply)
(exhales)
(Beckett) I THINK
WE'RE DONE HERE. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU. YOU KNOW,
AT LEAST DR. COSWAY
DIDN'T CHARGE MOT?ST-MINUT.
WHY NOT?
OH, SHE SAID SHE WAS GONNA
HAVE LUNCH WITH HER HUSBAND,
SO IT WAS TIME WELL SPENT.
THANK YOU, MR. HINKLE.
THANK YOU.
OH, AND BY THE WAY,
IT'S A COMMON MISTAKE,
BUT IT'S NOT IRONIC THAT
DR. COSWAY IS NOT HERE
FOR YOU TO LEAN ON.
IT'S JUST SIMPLY TRAGIC.
IT WOULD BE IRONIC IF HER DEATH
MADE YOU FEEL BETTER.
CASTLE.
JUST--YOU CAN...
WHAT'S WITH THE SUPER COP?
I HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
OKAY, THANK YOU.
I APPRECIATE IT.
WELL, I'M DOWN FOR $50.
YOU KNOW THAT.
(Castle) UH-HUH.
WELL... (clears throat)
SO WHAT YOU GOT?
I JUST GOT A PING
ON ASHLEY'S CREDIT CARD.
A LUNCH CHARGE AT PETIT BISTRO,
RIGHT NEXT DOOR TO HER OFFICE.
AND
THE HOSTESS CONFIRMED
THAT ASHLEY AND JASON WERE
HAVING LUNCH THERE ON FRIDAY.
AND THE ONLY REASON
SHE REMEMBERS IT
IS BECAUSE THEY WERE
MAKING KIND OF A SCENE.
HE'S OUR SCREAMER.
THEY WERE ARGUING ALL THE WAY
BACK TO THE OFFICE.
HE'S THE ONE SHE WAS GETTING
THE RESTRAINING ORDER AGAINST.
JASON'S ALIBI THAT HE WAS
AT THE GAME WITH HIS FRIEND
FEEL A LITTLE SQUISHY TO YOU?
LIKE A WORMY APPLE.
HEY, KARPOWSKI.
YO.
WHY DON'T WE TAKE A BETTER LOOK
AT JASON COSWAY?
HEY, MAN. THAT'S A SAFE BET.
YOU BETTER GO FOR IT.
WORK SITUATION, FINANCIALS
AND HOTEL BILLS.
(mouths words)
YEAH, OKAY. COPY THAT.
WANT A COFFEE?
(man) GIVE IT TO HIM.
NO. THANKS.
(man) ALL RIGHT, THANKS.
(officers speaking indistinctly)
(pen clatters)
HEY, STEGNER.
JUST... ADMIRING
THE GREAT BOARD WORK, BECKETT.
CARE TO SHARE
ANY INSIGHT?
I REALLY NEED TO...
GO FILE.
UH-HUH.
I'D BE MORE THAN HAPPY
TO TAKE THAT OFF YOUR HANDS.
(Castle speaks indistinctly)
SON OF A..!
WHAT IS THIS?
GIRL SCOUT COOKIE ORDERS.
HUH. GIRL SCOUT
COOKIE ORDERS.
YEAH, I'M JUST
HELPING OUT THE TROOP.
FUNNY. I DIDN'T REALIZE
ALEXIS WAS A GIRL SCOUT.
OH, I KNOW.
SHE'S GOT SO MANY ACTIVITIES,
I CAN BARELY KEEP TRACK.
FREAKIN' GREAT.
WHAT HAPPENED?
BALLISTICS SCREWED US.
OUR MUGGER'S GUN DOESN'T MATCH
THE BULLET TAKEN FROM OUR VIC.
OING ON?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
BETTING ON MURDER CASES,
GUYS? REALLY?
WHOA. WHAT?
THAT WOULD BE WRONG.
I'VE BEEN TELLING YOU,
IT'S GIRL SCOUT ORD--
GIRL SCOUT COOKIES
ARE SOLD IN FEBRUARY.
YOU GUYS SHOULD BE
ASHAMED OF YOURSELVES.
NOW GET BACK TO WORK.
(both mouth words)
(mouths words)
LISTEN... I'M SORRY.
I KNOW IT WAS WRONG.
I JUST THOUGHT--
BECKETT, YOU ARE NEVER
GONNA BELIEVE THIS.
OH, THE BAR ON UNBELIEVABLE
IS PRETTY HIGH RIGHT NOW.
VIC'S HUSBAND TOOK OUT
A $3-MILLION
LIFE INSURANCE POLICY
ON HIS WIFE LAST MONTH.
$100 ON US.
♪
THAT'S WHY NEW
Dove Style + Care
Whipped Cream Mousse
NOURISHES AND CONDITIONS
TO HELP KEEP CURLS WELL DEFINED
AND TOUCHABLY SOFT.
NEW Dove Style + Care
Whipped Cream Mousse.
BETTER STYLE
THROUGH BETTER CARE.
NEW Dove Style + Care
Whipped Cream Mousse.
(sighs) LOOK, UM,
THE LIFE INSURANCE
WAS ASHLEY'S IDEA, OKAY?
OKAY, FINE, JASON.
IT WAS ASHLEY
CAN ANYONE CONFIRM THAT?
YES, I'M SURE SOMEONE CAN.
MAYBE A FRIEND.
WELL, HER BEST FRIEND BRANDY
HAD NO IDEA
ABOUT THE LIFE INSURANCE,
BUT SHE DID KNOW ABOUT
A RESTRAINING ORDERR
THAT YOUR WIFE WAS TRYING
TO GET AGAINST YOU.
THAT'S... INSANE.
THAT IS ABSOLUTELY RIDICULOUS.
YOU WANT TO TELL US
ABOUT LAST FRIDAY?
WHAT ABOUT LAST FRIDAY?
ABOUT THE SCREAMING MATCH
AT LUNCH
THAT LED ALL THE WAY BACK
TO HER OFFICE.
WE HAVE MULTIPLE WITNESSES,
JASON.
OKAY. GREAT.
YOU HAVE WITNESSES.
WE HAD A F
YOU KNOW WHAT IT PROVES?
WE'RE MARRIED.
WHAT DID YOU FIGHT ABOUT?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THE FIGHT
WAS ABOUT. I CAN'T REMEMBER.
SEE, I'M HAVING A HARD TIME
BELIEVING THAT...
HOW DOES HE EVEN KNOW
WE'REGOING AFTEER SHE'S
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THE FIGHT
WAS ABOUT. I CAN'T REMEMBER.
SEE, I'M HAVING A HARD TIME
BELIEVING THAT...
AHH. NO WONDER SHE'S
GOING AFTER HIM SO HARD.
I WAS AT A BASKETBALL GAME.
OH, YES, THAT'S RIGHT.
WITH YOUR FRAT BUDDY SKIP.
YES, JURIES DO LOVE IT
WHEN FRIENDS ALIBI FRIENDS.
WHY DON'T YOU GET
THE HOT DOG GUY
TO VOUCH FOR ME, OKAY?
IF YOU TRUST HIM.
WHAT WAS YOUR SEAT NUMBER?
WHAT DO--EXCUSE ME?
COME ON.
IT WAS JUST LAST NIGHT.
DON'T TELL ME
YOU DON'T REMEMBER?
THEY WERE--THEY WERE SKIP'S
TICKETS. WHY DON'T YOU ASK HIM?
(Castle) DON'T TELL ME
FOR ONE SECOND
YOU DIDN'T HAVE TO GET UP
DURING THAT LAME HALFTIME SHOW
AND REMEMBER WHAT SECTION
TO GO BACK TO.
THE ONLY THING I REMEMBER
IS THE FACT THAT
WE WERE SITTING THERE
RIGHT BEHIND THE HOME BENCH.
OH, OKAY...
YOU EVER HAVE SEATS LIKE THAT?
(scoffs) YEAH, RIGHT.
SO DIVORCE ISN'T AN OPTION.
DIVORCE? DIVORCE?
I'M GOING, TOO, BRO.
I DIDN'T WANT A DIVORCE,
OKAY, PAL?!
AND I DIDN'T KILL MY WIFE!
(indistinct conversations)
SO CAN WE CHARGE HIM?
WE STILL NEED EVIDENCE.
I'M GONNA GET A WARRANT
AND SEE WHAT IT TURNS UP.
(man) AND HOW ABOUT LANDERS?
THE 6'2" GUARD...
ARE THEY WATCHING TV?
I'M AFRAID THEY'VE THROWN IN
THE PROVERBIAL TOWEL.
HUH.
HEY, GUYS.
EVERYTHING OKAY?
YEAH, WE'RE JUST, UH,
JUST ENJOYING LAST NIGHT'S GAME.
YEAH. ISN'T GREAT WHEN YOU
CAN GET IT ON DEMAND?
OOH, I LOVE THIS PART.
CHECK IT OUT.
(whistle blows)
(man) EVERYBODY'S
COVERED UP GOOD,
AND THERE YET IS
ANOTHER TIME-OUT.
WHOA. THAT'S THEIR
THIRD TIME-OUT.
YEAH, ALREADY,
AND THEY'RE JUST BARELY
HALFWAY THROUGH
THE FIRST HAL
YEAH, THAT WOULD BE,
WHAT, JUST BEFORE 8:00?H.
HALFWAY THROUGH
(Esposito) YEAH.
(remote beeps)
(chuckles)
THAT'S JASON COSWAY.
(Esposito) MM-HMM.
AND I BELIEVE THAT
THAT, MY FRIENDS,
IS THE DEFINITION OF
AN AIRTIGHT ALIBI. (crunches)
CASTLE, WHAT SIZE DRESS
DO YOU WEAR, 6, 8?
MNH-MNH.
16.
MM-HMM.
OH, YEAH.
DAD.S.
MM-HMM. YES.
YOU OKAY?
UH...
HAVE YOU EVER BEEN
REALLY SURE ABOUT SOMETHING,
AND THEN HAVE IT ALL
JUST FALL APART?
AS A MATTER OF FACT,
I HAVE.
OWEN?
IT WAS A TRAIN WRECK.
WHAT HAPPENED?
THALIA.
WHAT'S A THALIA?
SOME PERKY GIRL
WITH BIG... TEETH.
SHE CAME OVER TO OUR TABLE
GUSHING ABOUT HOW SHE AND OWEN
WENT TO CAMP CHUMASH TOGETHER
THIRD GRADE SUMMER,
AND HOW SHE WAS
HIS FIRST CRUSH.
THE WHOLE NIGHT WAS
ONE BIG WA
I'M SORRY, SWEETIE.
AND THE WEIRD PART
WAS THAT...
OWEN DIDN'T EVEN
REMEMBER HER.
NOT THAT IT STOPPED HIM
FROM BEING TOTALLY INTO IT.
I MEAN, EVEN IN THE TAXI BACK,
HE KEPT SAYING
HOW AMAZING IT WAS
THAT THEY MET
AFTER ALL THESE YEARS
AT SERENDIPITY.
HOW IT WAS SO SERENDIPITOUS.
SERENDIPITOUS.
HOW AM I SUPPOSED TO COMPETE
WITH THAT?
SORRY.
(lowered voice)
WHERE ARE YOU NOW?
YES, I'M ON THE ELEVATOR
RIGHT... NOW.
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
APOLOGIZING FOR THTCH A BREAK?
NO, BUT THE BOYS DID.
ANOTHER MUGGER?
I DON'T KNOW. BUT THEY LOOK
PRETTY HOT ON SOMETHING.
WHAT? WHAT DO YOU HAVE?
WHY DON'T YOU GO AHEAD
AND GIVE HIM
A LITTLE TASTE, BRO?
TURNS OUT OUR VIC HAD
A RENT-CONTROLLED APARTMENT.
STAYS IN THE FAMILY,
IT STAYS RENT CONTROLLED.
$562 A MONTH. 3-BEDROOM.
I'D KILL FOR THAT.
ACCORDING TO A NEIGHBOR,
VIC'S SON-IN-LAW
BORROWED MONEY FROM THE OLD MAN
A BUNCH OF TIMES OVER THE YEARS,
BUT RECENTLY, HE CUT HIM OFF.
SON-IN-LAW.
(cell phone rings and beeps)
RYAN.
REALLY? YEAH, WE'RE ON IT.
COME ON.
SOMETHING GOOD?
LET'S GO.
WH-WHAT IS IT?
WOULDN'T YOU LIKE TO KNOW?
(Castle) HEY, COME ON!
(pounds desk)
I GOT A BAD FEELING
ABOUT THIS.
ARE WE REALLY ROOTING
AGAINST SOLVING A MURDER?
WELL, I DON'T WANT
TO SHAVE MY HEAD. DO YOU?
WHY WOULD I SHAVE MY HEAD?
YOU'RE IN ON THE BET,
AREN'T YOU?
(cell phone ringing)
YEAH, BUT I DIDN'T REALIZE--
(imitates electric clippers)
(beep)
BECKETT.
OKAY.
WE'LL BE RIGHT THERE.
LANIE JUST FOUND SOMETHING
IN THE FORENSIC REPORT.
WELL, I HOPE IT'S BETTER
THAN THEIR SON-IN-LAW.
AND YOU'RE SURE IT WAS THEM?
(inhales deeply)
OKAY. THANKS.
I DON'T EVEN WANT TO KNOW.
TWO BARTENDERS
AND THE MANAGER
PUT FRANK'S SON-IN-LAW ERIC
AND DAUGHTER CHRISTINA UPTOWN
AT THEIR FRIEND EDDIE'S
BIRTHDAY PARTY AT DUBLIN HOUSE
FROM 9:15
TILL AFTER MIDNIGHT.
DUDE, IF I HAVE TO SHAVE
MY HEAD, IT'S GOING ON YOU.
(Castle)
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?ED US.
LANIE CALLED US.
NO, SHE CALLED US.
YEAH.
ACTUALLY, I CALLED BOTH OF YOU.
I THINK YOUR CASES
MIGHT BE CONNECTED.
So I get Claritin Clear...
...for strong, non-drowsy
relief of all my allergies...
...like dust...
...mold...
...pets...
...and pollen.
Looks good.
Thanks.
I Live Claritin Clear.
♪
[ Female Announcer ] MAY YOUR
HOLIDAYS BE MERRY AND BRIGHT.
MERRY PRINGLES.
I DIDN'T WANT TO CHANGE
TOOTHPASTES...
I ALREADY HAD A PRODUCT
THAT MADE MY MOUTH FEEL CLEAN...
THE FIRST THING HE RECOMMENDED
WAS SENSODYNE.
IT HELPS
WITH THE SENSITIVITY ISSUES
AND IT SATISFIES THE NEEDS
THAT I WOULD LOOK FOR
E.
AND WITH MY BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CREDIT CARD,
I LOVE 'EM EVEN MORE.
I EARN 1% CASH BACK EVERYWHERE,
EVERY TIME.
2% ON GROCERIES.
3% ON GAS.
AUTOMATICALLY.
NO HOOPS TO JUMP THROUGH.
THAT'S 1% BACK ON...
[ toy robot sounds ]
2% ON PUMPKIN PIE.
AND APPLE.
3% BACK ON 4 TRIPS
TO THE AIRPORT.
IT'S AS EASY AS...
-[ man ] 1...
-[ woman ] 2...
[ woman ] 3.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CARD.
APPLY ONLINE OR AT
A BANK OF AMERICA NEAR YOU.
♪
THAT'S WHY NEW
Dove Style + Care
Whipped Cream Mousse
NOURISHES AND CONDITIONS
TO HELP KEEP CURLS WELL DEFINED
AND TOUCHABLY SOFT.
NEW Dove Style + CareCrea.
BETTER STYLE
THROUGH BETTER CARE.
TOMATO,
OBVIOUSLY.
HAHA. THERE'S MORE
THAN THAT THOUGH,
THERE'S A KICK TO IT.
WAHLALALALALLALA!
SMOOTH, BUT CRISP.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE DRINKING
A FOOD THAT'S A DRINK,
OR A DRINK THAT'S A FOOD,
WOOOOOH!
[ Male AnnounceDESCRIBABLE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
WE WABOUT SOMETHING NO ONE
ASKIWANTS TO TALK ABOUT.ANKLY
IT'S TIME TO GET REAL ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENS IN THE BATHROOM.
ESY STUFF
STOP ALL THE CUTESY STUFF
AND START TALKING ABOUT
WHAT YOU REALLY WANT
FROM YOUR TOILET PAPER.
IT'S TIME TO TALK ABOUT CLEAN.
FEELING CLEAN IS SO IMPORTANT.
QUILTED NORTHERN SOFT AND STRONG
IS STRONGER THAN THE
LEADING VALUE BRAND,
TO HELP PROTECT
AGAINST BREAKTHROUGH.
FOR MYSELF, FOR MY FAMILY,
IT KI USE QUILTED NORTHERN.
QUILTED NORTHERN
SOFT AND STRONG,
PROTECTION FOR A CONFIDENT
CLEAN OR YOUR MONEY BACK.
Want to start the day
with something heart healthy
and delicious?
You're a talking bee...
Honey Nut Cheerios
has whole grain oats
that can help
lower cholesterol.
and it tastes good?
Sure does!
Right...
♪
Wow.
Delicious, right?
Yeah.
It's the honey,
it makes it taste so...
♪
Well, would you
look at the time...
What's the rush?
Be happy. Be healthy.
PERLMUTTER WAS GIVING ME
THE RUNDOWN
ON RYAN AND ESPOSITO'S
MUGGING CASE
WHEN A CERTAIN FORENSIC DETAIL
POPPED OUT AT ME.
ORTHO WHAT NOW? ACID.?
IT'S THE FANCY TERM
FOR SALTWATER COMPOUND.
THAT'S NOT VERY SPECIFIC.
TRUE.
BUT WE IDENTIFIED THE DIATOMS
IN THE SAMPLE AS WELL,
WHICH MAKEIFIC.
IT NARROWS IT DOWN
TO A SINGLE BODY OF WATER.
OH, SO OUR GUY TOOK A SWIM?
NOT QUITE.
IT WAS ONLY TRACE AMOUNTS.
BUT WE FOUND ORTHOSILICIC ACID
WITH THE EXACT SAME DIATOMS
ON ASHLEY COSWAY AS WELL.
BOTH VICTIMS HAD CONTACT
WITH THE SAME BODY OF WATER?
DIRECT CONTACT.
WHAT ARE THE ODDS?
IT'D BE LIKE FINDING THE SAME
FINGERPRINT ON BOTH BODIES.
DO WE KNOW
WHAT BODY OF WATER?
NO, I WOULD NEED A SAMPLE
TO TEST IT AGAINST.
CASTLE.
COULD IT BE
A SMALL BODY OF WATER?
SURE, AS LONG
AS IT'S SALTWATER.
(papers rustling)
DR. COSWAY'S FISH TANK.
CHECK OUT NEMO.
CLOWN FISH
NEED SALTWATER TO LIVE.
OKAY, BUT HOW DID THIS GET
ON BOTH OF OUR VICS?
WOULDN'T THEY HAVE HAD TO
STICK THEIR HANDS IN THERE
O
YOU SEE THAT SALT ENCRUSTATION
ALONG THE TOP?
YEAH.
THE PUMP JUST KICKS IT
INTO THE AIR.
YEAH, ANYONE WHO SPENT TIME
IN THAT OFFICE
WOULD HAVE TRACE AMOUNTS
OF THAT TANK-SPECIFIC
SALTWATER COMPOUND ON THEM.
SO THEN FRANK HAD TO
HAVE BEEN IN ASHLEY'S OFFICE
SOMETIME BEFORE
HE WAS MURDERED.
IT'S POSSIBLE, BUT REMEMBER,
ASHLEY WAS MURDERED FIRST.
THEN OUR PERP WAS IN THERE.
THAT'S WHERE HE GOT
THE COMPOUND ON HIM.
THEN HE TRANSFERRED IT
TO FRANK
WHEN HE TOOK HIS WATCH
AND WALLET.
WHICH MEANS BOTH OF OUR VICS
WERE KILLED BY THE SAME PERSON.
I THOUGHT
DAD WAS MUGGED.
YEAH, LIKE--LIKE RANDOMLY.
WE DON'T BELIEVE
IT WAS RANDOM ANYMORE.
MR. COSWAY'S WIFE ASHLEY
WAS KILLED EARLIER THAT NIGHT.
WE THINK THE SAME PERSON
KILLED YOUR FATHER
AND THEN TRIED TO STAGE IT
AS IF THERE WERE
TWO ISOLATED INCIDENTS.
WE'RE TRYING TO FIND
A CONNECTION BETWEEN THEM.
THIS IS MRS. COSWAY.
AND THIS IS MR. ANDERSON.
DO EITHER OF THEM
LOOK FAMILIAR?
NO. (sighs) NOT AT ALL.
I'M SORRY.
MRS. COSWAY
WAS A THERAP
DID YOUR FATHER
EVER GO TO THERAPY?
DAD? NO. (ch
NO DISRESPECT TO YOUR WIFE,
BUT HE UFF. FOR THAT KIND .
WELL, THIS IS A LIST
OF MRS. COSWAY'S PATIENTS.
WOULD YOU MIND
TAKING A LOOK AT THE NAMES,
SEE IF YOU RECOGNIZE
ANY OF T
I-I DON'T THINK SO.
NO.
NO, I...
TAKE YOUR TIME.
DO YOU REALLY THINK
THERE'S A CONNECTION HERE?
I MEAN, WE--WE LIVE IN
DIFFERENT PARTS OF THE CITY,
WE'RE...
GO AH     YOU KNOW,
WE WORK AT DIFFERENT PLACES,
WE'RE...
GO AHEAD. YOU COULD SAY IT.
WE'RE BLACK AND YOU'RE WHITE.
NO, I--NO, I'M JUST SAYING,
WE'RE DIFFERENT.
THAT'S ALL I WAS SAYING.
THEY MAY HAVE INADVERTENTLY
WITNESSED SOMETHING
OR BEEN PRIVY
TO SOME INFORMATION
THAT SOMEONE VERY POWERFUL
WANTED TO KEEP UNDER WRAPS.
THERE ARE ANY NUMBER
OF POSSIBILITIES.
WE JUST WANT--
(Christina) GROVNER.
WHAT WAS THAT?
UH, THIS NAME--GROVNER.
IT--IT KINDA RINGS A BELL.
DO YOU REMEMBER
ABOUT FIVE YEARS BACK,
GOT INVOLVED.
SOME KID'S DAD
I THINK HIS NAME WAS GROVNER.V.
WE'LL GET A WARRANT
FOR HIS PATIENT FILE.
IF THERE'S A CONNECTION,
WE'LL FIND IT.
SO... THE PRINCIPAL
AT I.S. 1-6-1
SAID THAT GROVNER
ASSAULTED YOUR VIC
AFTER MR. ANDERSONBUSE.
WHICH IS WHSUSPICION OY
GROVNER AND HIS WIFE
WENT TO COUPLES' COUNSELING.
APPARENTLY IT DIDN'T GO
TOO WELL,
BECAUSE THEY ENDED UP FILING
FOR DIVORCE, AND GET THIS--
MRS. COSWAY TESTIFIED
AGAINST GROVNER IN COURT.
SO GROVNER HAD REASON
TO GO AFTER BOTH OUR VICTIMS.
YEAH, WENT AWAY FOR FIVE YEARS
FOR DOMESTIC ABUSE.
SAYS RIGHT HERE
HE WAS RELEASED LAST MONTH.
WHAT ARE THE ODDS, HUH,
TWO PEOPLE FROM OPPOSITE LIVES
BEING CONNECTED
BY ONE JACKHOLE?
JUST DEMONSTRATES THAT
ANY TWO PEOPLE CAN BE CONNECTED.
YEAH, LIKE THE MOVIE "CRASH."
"CRASH" IS OVERRATED.
ACTUALLY, IT'S MORE LIKE
SIX DEGREES OF KEVIN BACON.
(cell phone beeps)
I GOT A QUESTION.
NOW THAT WE'RE ALL WORKING
THE SAME CASE,
DOES THAT MEAN THE BET'S OFF?
HELL, YEAH.
(shouting indistinctly)
(tires squealing)
YOU GOT THE ADDRESS?
(Esposito)
YEAH, IT'S AROUND BACK.NNERS
BANNER DAY. GONNA CLOSE
TWO CASES WITH ONE ARREST.
JUST YET, BOYSN'T DECORATE .
IT MIGHT BE A COINCIDENCE.
OH, COME ON,
DEBBIE DOWNER.
THERE ARE NO SUCH THINGS
AS COINCIDENCES IN MURDER CASES.
HOW MANY TIMES
DO I HAVE TO TELL YOU?
I MEAN,
IT'S THE BASIC FOUNDATION
OF EVERY CRIME BOOK
I'VE EVER WRITTEN--
."
(whispering) THAT'S HIM.
READY?
PUT YOUR HANDS UP!
LET'S SEE 'EM, BUDDY.
KEEP 'EM UP.
(Esposito) GET YOUR HANDS UP!
HANDS WHERE WE CAN SEE 'EM!
(man) WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
WESLEY GROVNER,
I'M DETECTIVE KATE BECKETT.
WHAT, DID I MISS
ANOTHER PAROLE MEETING?
HE'S CLEAN... SO TO SPEAK.
WHERE WERE YOU
LAST TUESDAY NIGHT?
AM I BEING PUNKED?
IF BY "PUNKED" YOU MEAN
ARRESTED FOR MURDER, YEAH.
YOU THINK I WENT SOMEWHERE
TUESDAY NIGHT
AND KILLED SOMEBODY?
ACTUALLY, TWO SOMEBODIE
(laughs)
HEY, I'M HOUDINI.
NICE BLING, HUH?
(ankle bracelet beeping)
OOPS.
CHECK THIS OUT.
(alarm blares)
(alarm stops)
THIS STOOP
IS THE EDGE OF MY EARTH
SINCE I BUSTED PAROLE
A WEEK AGO.
WHATEVER YOU THINK I DID,
I AIN'T YOUR GUY.
(ankle bracelet beeping)
THAT'S QUITE THE COINCIDE
♪
[ Female Announcer ] MAY YOUR
HOLIDAYS BE MERRY AND BRIGHT.
MERRY PRINGLES.
THAT
Dove Style + Care
Frizz Free Cream Serum
NOURISHES AND CONDITIONS,
KEEPING HAIR SMOOTH SHINY
AND FREE FROM FLYAWAYS.
e
Frizz Free Cream Serum.e +e
Frizz Free Cream Serum
NOURISHES AND CONDITIONS,
BETTER STYLE
THROUGH BETTER CARE.
♪ DON'T KNOW WHAT I'D DO
♪ I'D HAVE NOTHING TO PROVE
♪ I'D HAVE NOTHING TO LOSE
♪ I'D BE ALL LOST AT SEA
♪ WITH NO REASON
TO MAKE IT THROUGH ♪
[ Male Announcer ]
INTRODUCING THE Celebration
Diamond Collection.
♪ IF IT WASN'T FOR YOU
[ Male Announcer ]
DIAMONDS SO EXPERTLY CUT,
HEM FOR LIFE.
Zales IS THE DIAMOND STORE.
LET LOVE SHINE.
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
YOUR FAVORITE HOLIDAY FLAVORS
ARE HERE...
WITH SOME NEW ONES TO LOVE.
♪
TRY NEW SUGAR FREE
PUMPKIN SPICE...
AND PECAN PRALINE.
THE GIFT OF GREAT TASTE
IS JUST A CLICK AWAY.
GET YOUR COUPON
AT TASTELIFT.COFFEE-MATE.COM.
NESTLE.
GOOD FOOD. GOOD LIFE.
I'VE BEEN FORTUNATE TO WIN
ON GOLF'S BIGGEST STAGES.
BUT WHEN JOINT PAIN
AND STIFFNESS
FROM PSORIATIC ARTHRITIS HIT,
EVEN THE SMALLEST THINGS
BECAME DIFFICULT.
I FINALLY UNDERSTOOD WHAT
SERIOUS JOINT PAIN IS LIKE.WHAT
FROM PSORIATIC ARTHRITIS HIT,
I TALKED TO MY RHEUMATOLOGIST
AND HE PRESCRIBED Enbrel.
Enbrel CAN HELP RELIEVE
PAIN, STIFFNESS,
AND STOP JOINT DAMAGE.
BECAUSE Enbrel, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS,
SOMETIMES FATAL EVENTS
INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS,
LYMPHOMA, OTHER CANCERS,
INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.D
BEFORE STARTING Enbrel,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START Enbrel IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON Enbrel, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING, OR PALENESS.
[ Phil ]
GET BACK TO THE THINGS
THAT MATTER MOST.
ASK YOUR RHEUMATOLOGIST
IF Enbrel IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
[ Doctor ]
Enbrel, THE NUMBER ONE
BIOLOG MEDICINE
PRESCRIBED BY RHEUMATOLOGISTS.
[ Doctor ]
Enbrel, THE NUMBER ONE
BIOLOG MEDICINE
(Martha) HOW DARE YOU!
HOW DARE YOU...
(thump)
(Alexis) OW.
TAKE MY DRESS!
YOU'RE AS THOUGHTLESS
AS YOUR FATHER!
I'M SORRY! I--STOP! NO.
YOU'RE A BEASTIE!
NO! I DIDN'T--I DIDN'T THINK
IT WAS A BIG DEAL!
I OUGHT TO BREAK
YOUR LITTLE WRISTS.
NO.
MOTHER,
HAVE YOU FINALLY...
HAVE I FINALLY WHAT,
DEAR?
HEY, DAD.
(exhales)
YOU'RE REHEARSING.
LIEVED US.CK.
OH,
MARVELOUS. OH, MY GOD!
THAT'S MARVELOUS.
NO, I AM A BETTER ACTRESS
THAN I THINK I AM.
OH!
(chuckles)
YOU OKAY, DAD?
YOU LOOK UPSET.
TURNS OUT SOMETHING
I WAS SO SURE OF
WAS JUST A COINCIDENCE.
OH, IS THIS ABOUT
THE MURDER?
EXACTLY.
IT SO HAPPENS THAT OUR
TWO VICTIMS WERE CONNECTED.
IT JUST HAD NOTHING TO DO
WITH THEIR DEATHS.
YOU KNOW, I BET
IF YOU LOOKED HARD ENOUGH,
YOU'D FIND A CONNECTION
BETWEEN EVERYBODY IN THIS CITY.
I MEAN, THAT'S THE GREAT THIN T
YEAH, AND IF THERE WASN'T
A CONNEC
YOU COULD ALWAYS PRETEND
THERE'S ONE.
BESIDES THE REHEARSAL,
WE HAVE ANOTHER DRAMA
GOING ON HERE THIS EVENING.
OH, OWEN?
YOU KNOW HOW THALIA SAID
SHE HAD A CRUSH ON OWEN
AT CAMP CHUMASH?
SERENDIPITY
AT SERENDIPITY, YEAH.
NO. MORE LIKE SUBTERFUGE
AT SERENDIPITY.
SHE NEVER EVEN WENT
TO CAMP CHUMASH,
BUT HER FRIEND DID.
AND THALIA WANTED TO MEET OWEN,
SO SHE STAGED THE WHOLE THING.
OH, THAT IS SO...
BUDDING SOCIOPATH.
I KNEW IT COULDN'T BE
A COINCIDENCE.
I MEAN, REALLY,
WHAT ARE THE ODDS?
YEAH. WHAT ARE THE ODDS?
(Castle) HEY.
HEY, CASTLE.
HOW YOU DOING?
WELL, FOR A SECOND LAST NIGHT,
I THOUGHT MY MOTHER
WAS BEATING ALEXIS, SO...
YEAH. WELL, GROVNER WAS
A HE BY THE WAY.R ALL OF US. BY,
WELL, "CRASH"
WAS ON THIS MORNING,
FOLLOWED BY "FOOTLOOSE,"
SO I GUESS
ANYTHING CAN HAPPEN.
(chuckles)
ARE YOU OKAY?
YEAH.
IT'S JUST, THIS ONE
REMINDS ME OF MY MOM'S CASE.
WHAT FRANK ANDERSON'S FAMILY
MUST BE GOING THROUGH,
ESPECIALLY CHRISTINA...
MOURNING HER DAD'S DEATH
THAT IT WASN'T.AS RANDOM,   T
I GUESS YOU COULD SAY,
WHAT DOES IT MATTER?
THE PERSON THAT YOU LOVE
IS DEAD.
BUT KNOWING WHY MATTERS.
YO. FISH TANK'S A BUST.
WHAT?
LANIE CALLED.
WATER SAMPLE IS NOT A MATCH.
CAN YOU BELIEVE THAT?
WE'RE NOWHERE.
TOO GOOD TYEAH, GROVNER WAS A.
WHAT IS IT
WITH THESE T NOT ALMOST.
YEAH, AND YOU GUYS
AND THE HUSBAND.
I WAS SURE IT WAS HIM,
AND YOUR SON-IN-LAW.
(Ryan) I KNOW. SAME DEAL.
FELT IT.
OKAY, IT'S NOT THE FISH TANK,
BUT THEY ARE CONNECTED.
WE JUST HAVE TO
FIGURE OUT HOW.
IT'S JUST, WE'VE BEEN OVER
THESE CASES SO MANY TIMES,
IT'S HARD
TO SEE STRAIGHT ANYMORE.
ALL RIGHT. (sighs)
WE'LL START OVER. FRESH EYES.
YOU TAKE OUR MURDER.
WE'LL TAKE YOURS.
(Esposito) ALL RIGHT.
WHOA, WHOA,
WHOA, WHOA, W
SAY THAT AGAIN.
YOU          WHOA, WHOA,
WHOA, WHOA, W
YOU TAKE OUR MURDER.
WE'LL TAKE YOURS.
COULD IT BE THAT EASY?
YOU TAKE MINE.
I'LL TAKE YOURS.
WHAT ARE YOU GETTING AT,
CASTLE?
"STRANGERS ON A TRAIN."
THE HITCHCOCK MOVIE?
I'M PARTIAL TO THE NOVEL BY
PATRICIA HIGHSMITH, BUT, YES.
WE HAVE TWO STRONG SUSPECTS,
BUT WITH AIRTIGHT ALIBIS, RIGHT?
(Esposito) RIGHT.
WE KNOW THEY'RE CONNECTED.
WHAT IF THE CONNECTION
IS THE KILLERS?
JASON AND ERIC COMMITTED
EACH OTHER'S MURDERS.
AND MADE SURE THEY HLIBI
FOR THE MURDER THEY KNEW
THEY'D BE SUSPECTED OF.
IT'S NOT OUR VICTIMS
WHO ARE CONNECTED.
IT'S OUR MURDERERS.
CRISSCROSS.
(Beckett) OKAY, SO WE KNOW JASON
WAS AT THE GARDEN
WATCHING THE GAME
TILL IT FINISHED AT 10:00.
AND THEN HE MADE THROM ASHLEE
AT 11:47.
THE GARDEN IS ON 32nd.
HER OFFICE IS ON 18th.
WOULD'VE TAKEN HIM
MAX 20 MINUTES.
SO WHY DID IT TAKE HIM
TWO HOURS?
BECAUSE, ESPOSITO,
HE JUMPED IN A CAB,
WENT UPTOWN, KILLED FRANK.
WHICH HAPPENED AT 11:00.
HE EASILY MAKES IT BACK
TO HIS WIFE'S OFFICE
IN TIME TO FIND HER BODY
AT 11:47.
AND WE KNOW THAT ERIC
AND ASHLEY'S T OF WORK AT 6:03)
(Beckett)
AND ASHLEY'S KILLED AT 8:00.
HE SHOWS UP FOR THE PARTY
AT THE BAR AT 9:15.
SOMETHING TELLS ME THEIR ALIBIS
ARE NOT GOING TO BE SO AIRTIGHT
FOR THE OTHER MURDERS.
MR. COSWAY, WE WERE
JUST COMING TO SEE YOU.
OH, HEY.
YOU GUYS HAVE NEWST
I MEAN, IS IT THE OLD PATIENT
JUST   OF ASHLEY'S?YOU.
THAT TURN OUT
TO BE ANYTHING OR--
NO, BUT WE ARE
MAKING PROGRESS.
OKAY. UH, WHAT CAN I DO
FOR YOU?
JUST LIKE TO ASK YOU
A FEW QUESTIONS
ABOUT THE NIGHT OF THE MURDER.
DO YOU GUYS HAVE
ANY SUSPECTS AT ALL YET OR--
WE'RE LOOKING AT SOMEONE
RIGHT NOW.
OKAY.
WELL, ACTUALLY, I HAVE TO MEET
THE MOVERS AT ASHLEY'S OFFICE.
SO IF YOU DON'T MIND
WALKING WITH ME...
NOT AT ALL.
COULD YOU TELL US WHAT YOU DID
RIGHT AFTER THE BASKETBALL GAME?
AFTER?
WELL, WHY DO YOU ASK?
WE'RE JUST TRYING TO GET
OUR TIMELINE STRAIGHT.
YOU'RE NOT ACCUSING ME OF
KILLING MY WIFE AGAIN, ARE YOU?
I CAN ASSURE YOU
THAT WE ARE 100% CERTAIN
YOU DID NOT KILL ASHLEY.
IT'S JUST,
THE NIGHT OF THE MURDER,
YOU SAID THAT YOU WERE
ON YOUR WAY TO PICK HER UP
RIGHT AFTER THE GAME.
YEAH, SO?
WELL, THEN WHY DID IT
TAKE YOU TWO HOURS
TO GET FROM THE GARDEN
TO 18th STREET?
LOOK, I KNEW ASH WANTED
TO WORK LATE, RIGHT?
I DIDN'T WANT TO BOTHER HER,
SO I JUST KILLED SOME TIME.
OOH.
I DIDN'T WANT TO BOTHER HER,
SORRY. GO AHEAD.ILLED SOME TIME.
SORROOH.
UH, AND THEN I STOPPED
AT A NEWSSTAND.
WHERE?
UH, SOMEWHERE ON 7th.
MAYBE IT WAS 26th.
I DON'T KNOW. ANYWAY, I BOUGHT
MYSELF A SLICE OF PIZZA...
AT RAY'S.
ORIGINAL FAMOUS
OR FAMOUS ORIGINAL?
THERE'S ONE ON 28th.
AND THERE'S ONE ON 23rd.
I CAN'T REMEMBER WHICH.
I'M A LITTLE, UH,
CONFUSED HERE.
YOU KNOW, THERE IS SOMEBODY
OUT THERE THAT KILLEERE IS SO
MR. COSWAY, WE'RE JUST
TRYING TO FIGURE THIS OUT.
UM, I, UH, AFTER THAT,
I WENT HO
IS THERE ANYONE
THAT CAN VOUCH FOR THAT?
YEAH, I'M SURE
SOMEBODY IN MY BUILDING.
THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR YOUR TIME.
OF COURSE.
(water taxi horn sounds)
(man) LAST CALL FOR EXPRESS
SERVICE TO WALL STREET.
LAST CALL, EXPRESS SERVICE
TO WALL STREET.
LAST CALL, EXPRESS FERRY
FROM CHELSEA PIER 66,
GREENWICH VILLAGE
TO THE WORLD FINANCIAL CENTER.
LAST CALL.
LOOKS LIKE WE FOUND
OUR BODY OF WATER.
STRANGERS ON A BOAT?
AND THEN THERE'S JUICY CHICKEN
WITH BEST FOODS
♪
BEST FOODS IS THE SECRET
TO MAKING
PARMESAN CRUSTED CHICKEN...
[ bell dings ]
...SO CRISPY
SO JUICY
SO DELICIOUS
IT'S YOUR SECRET
TO MAKING DINNER
DISAPPEAR
BEST FOODS.
BRING OUT THE BEST
TO MAKING DINNER
DISAPPEAR
FOR STRONG BEAUTIFUL HAIR.
-IT TURNS OUT...
-WE WERE WORKING AT...
AT THE WRONG END OF HAIR.
[ Male Announcer ]
INTRODUCING CLEAR.
IT FEEDS YOUR SCALP.
CLEAR GIVES YOU STRONGER
MORE BEAUTIFUL HAIR.
[ Heidi ] CLEAR SCALP
AND HAIR BEAUTY THERAPY.
CLEAR GIVES YOU STRONGER
MORE BEAUTIFUL HAIR.
SO WHAT'S THE VERDICT?
ERIC MARX TAKES THE SAME
WATER TAXI TO WORK, TOO.
"BAM," SAID THE LADY.
THERE'S OUR CONNECTION.
OH, NO. IT GETS BETTER.
LANIE RAN THE SUBSTANCE
ON OUR VICS
AGAINST THE HUDSON RIVER WATER.
IT'S A MATCH.
MARX GETS ON
THE BOAT UPTOWN,
COSWAY JOINS HIM
AT CHELSEA PIERS,
AND THEY RIDE TO PIER 11
MAYBE THEY START TALKING--LKI,
MAYBE ABOUT THE YANKEE BULLPEN,
MAYBE ABOUT
THE ATTRACTIVE SECRETARY
LEANING UP AGAINST THE RAILING.
OH, AND JASON STARTS GRUMBLING
ABOUT HIS WIFE.
ERIC MAYBE MENTIONS
HOW HE COVETS FRANK'S APARTMENT.
YEAH, WELL, THERE'S
AN OPEN UPPER DECK.
I FIGURE THAT'S WHERE THEY WERE
DOING THEIR PLOTTIN'.
AND HOW THE WATER
FROM THE HUDSON
GOT ON BOTH OF THEM.
IT GETS TRANSFERRED FROM
ERIC MARX'S JACKET AND GLOVES
TO ASHLEY COSWAY
WHEN THEY STRUGGLE.
THEN TO FRANK ANDERSON
WHEN JASON COSWAY SWIPES
HIS WATCH AND  CIRCUMSTANTIAL.
THE D.A. WILL NEVER BUY IT
WITHOUT HARD EVIDENCE
OR A CONFESSION.
(Esposito) OH, WE'RE GONNA GET
A CONFESSION.
(mutters)
(scoffs)
NOT IF WE GET ONE FIRST.
SO... BET'S BACK ON?
YOU BET YOUR BRITCHES,
THE BET IS BACK ON.
WHAT ARE THE ODDS?
(Jason) YOU GUYS REALLY THINK
A JURY IS GONNA BELIEVE
IN SUCH A CRAZY STORY
LIKE THIS, HUH?
JURIES ARE SMART.
YEAH. YEAH, THEY ARE.
BUT YOU SEE,
THEY'RE GONNA HAVE TO DO
TWO SEPARATE TRIALS HERE.
AND THE PROSECUTOR IS GONNA
HAVE TO CONVINCE THEMLLED SO
THAT I KILLED SOMEONE
WHO I HAVE NO CONNECTION TO
DEAD.ATSOEVER
TO WANT DEAD.
AND TO ME, THAT'S RIDICULOUS.
SOUNDS LIKE YOU'VE GIVEN THIS
SOME SERIOUS THOUGHT,
MR. COSWAY.
CUTE.
BUT WRONG.
WITH ERIC MARX
ON THE DECK OF THAT BOAT.
DON'T CRACK. NO ONE WILL EVER
BE ABLE TO PROVE WHAT YOU DID.
I TOLD YOU GUYS ALREADY,
I ONLY MET HIM THE OTHER DAY.
YOU RODE THE SAME WATER TAXI
TO WORK EVERY DAY.
AND SO DOES A HUNDRED
OTHER PEOPLE... EVERY DAY.
IT WAS YOUR IDEA, WASN'T IT?
REALLY?
YEAH.
THERE'S ALWAYS ONE ALPHA
IN EVERY CONSPIRACY,
AND THAT WAS YOU.
ERIC WAS MALLEABLE,
WASN'T HE?
AND THAT SUITED YOU
JUST FINE.
HMM.
BUT ASHLEY WASN'T, WAS SHE?
SHE WAS A STRONG,
PROFESSIONAL WOMAN--
A PSYCHOLOGIST, NO LESS.
YOU COULDN'T JUST
PUSH HER AROUND.
THEN WHY DID I MARRY HER?
THAT'S THE QUESTION
YOU ASKED YOURSELF EVERY DAY,
ISN'T IT?
BECAUSE YOU'D REALIZED,
YOU DIDN'T WANT A WIFE.
YOU WANTED A PUPPY.
NOW YOU GET A JUDGE WITH
POLITICAL ASPIRATIONS, BRO--
YEAH, WE'RE TALKING
DEATH PENALTY.
NEW YORK'S STILL
A LETHAL INJECTION STATE.
NOW YOU CONFESS,
YOU COP A PLEA,
THAT'S A DIFFERENT STORY.
YOU'RE GONNA SAVE THE STATE
ALL SORTS OF MONEY ON A TRIAL.
YEAH. PRACTICALIFE.
YEAH, AND TO GET OFF WITH JUST-
AND THEN THE JUDGE
CAN GET HIS POLITICAL BONES
ON SOMEONE ELSE,
NOW MY RIGHTS,
NO, I-I KNOW MY RIGHTS,
ALL RIGHT?E.
SO YOU CAN STOP WITH THIS
WHOLE GOOD COP/BAD--
IT'S GOOD YOU KNOW
Y
BECAUSE YOUR BUDDY JASON
JUST ROLLED ON YOU.
OH, MAN. COME ON.
(Castle) OH, YEAH. COSWAY
JUST SIGNED HIS CONFESSION.
COPPED A NICE LITTLE PLEA
AT YOUR EXPENSE. SORRY.
TOLD YOU WE'D GET
OUR GUY FIRST.
NO, NO, WAIT! WAIT, WAIT.
(panting)
IT WAS--IT WAS HIS IDEA,
NOT MINE.
HE PLANNED THE WHOLE THING.
♪
(officers speaking indistinctly)
(Esposito)
THIS IS TO TRANSCRIBE,
AND THIS IS TO FILE.
YO, RYAN, YOU WERE
ON FIRE IN THERE.
NEW NICKNAME--ICEPOSITO.
EXCELLENT WORK, DETECTIVE.
YEAH, WELL, ONCE WE REALIZED
THAT JASON WAS THE ALPHA
AND WOULDN'T BREAK,
IT WAS OBVIOUS THAT ERIC
WAS THE WEAK LINK.
(Ryan) NICE.
WHEN YOU GUYS CAME IN THE ROOM,
AND WE KNEW YOU WERE PLAYING,
EVERYTHING JUST KINDA...
YEAH. THAT'S RIGHT. OF COURSE,
WE WERE RIGHT WITH YOU GUYS.
OH, PLEASE.
THAT WAS THE WHOLE POINT
WAS THAT YOU WEREN'T IN ON IT.
THAT'S HOW WE SOLD IT.
WELL, THAT'S NEITHER HERE
NOR THERE,
BECAUSE WE WON THE BET.
HOW'S THAT?
(Esposito) OUR GUY BROKE.
YEAH, BECAUSE WE BROKE HIM.
UH, SO WHAT?
IT'S LIKE SOCCER.
YOU SCORE IN OUR GOAL,
IT'S STILL OUR POINT.
SOCCER, REALLY FOR ME. GO.
WELL, THEN HOW ABOUT BASEBALL?
'CAUSE THIS TEAM JUST KNOCKED IT
OUT OF THE PARK.
histles)ing) imitate crowd chee)
YEAH, BUT OUR TEAM
WAS SUPPOSED TO BE UP AT BAT.
AGAIN WITH THAT ONE?
YOUR TEAM NEVER MADE IT
TO THE FIELD
BECAUSE THEY WERE TOO SCARED
TO GET OFF THE BUS.
(laughs)
(Esposito) UH, CASTLE,
OUR TEAM DROVE THE BUS.
(Castle laughs) YEAH,
WELL, THEN HOW ABOUT NASCAR?
AS OUR CAR
FLEW TO THE CHECKERED LINE,
YOU GUYS CRASHED AND BURNED.
(Beckett) UNDER MOON.
THAT'S JUST CORNY. NEXT TIME
YOU WANT TO BET FOR REAL...
Here's a better idea.
Pillsbury Grands!
Flaky Layers Biscuits
In just 15 minutes
the light delicate layers
add a layer of warmth
to your next dinner.
Pillsbury Grands Biscuits
Let the making begin.
FASTER THAN MANDY CAN HANG UP
ON MR. MONDAY.
YOU HANG UP FIRST.
[ Female Announcer ]
IN JUST 60 SECONDS, YOU'VE GOT
SNACK-DEFYING, SATISFYING
TOTINO'S PIZZA ROLLS.
[ ringing ]
IT'S ON. LET'S ROLL.
YOU CHOOSE WHICH ONE OF US
RUNS THE PRACTICE.
CONGRATULATIONS, BOSS.
HELLO, PETER.
MEG?
(Violet) HOW DO YOU KNOW PETE?
(Meg) WE WERE RESIDENTS
TOGETHER.
AGAIN WITH THE TALKING?
I'M SERIOUS. WE'RE GONNA
GET TO KNOW EACH OTHER.
♪
I GOT IT.
HA HA! I GOT IT.
(grunts)
OH. OH, OH, SORRY.
ARE YOU STILL WORKING?
OKAY, I FIGURED IT OUT.