Ty:
YOU GUYS ARE GONNA GET TO SEE
YOUR FRIEND J.R. MARTINEZ.
HOW'S EVERYTHING?
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
ALL RIGHT.
MICHAEL, THIS LOOKS INCREDIBLE.
IS THIS AWESOME?
YEAH.
PRETTY SURE
THIS IS THE BIGGEST FLAG
IN ANYBODY'S FRONT YARD
IN TEXAS.
I'M TELLING YOU, MAN, AND
THEY'RE DEFINITELY GONNA
CUT BACK ON HIS WATER BILL
BECAUSE YOU DON'T HAVE TO PUT
A BUNCH OF SOD OUT HERE.
YEAH, THIS IS
DROUGHT-TOLERANT.
THIS IS GREAT. AT LEAST
HE WON'T HAVE TO COME OUT HERE
AND TRY TO WATER AND MOW
A BUNCH OF GRASS.
NO, NO, NO, NO.
COOL. LET'S GET THAT.
I'LL GET SOME MORE STONES.
AWESOME. THANKS.
THIS LOOKS AMAZING, YOU GUYS.
THANK YOU!
Man: MOVING FORWARD
WITH OUR SOLAR PANELS.
HOW BIG?
WHAT ARE WE LOOKING AT?
WE'RE LOOKING AT 5.7
KILOWATTS -- 5,700 KILOWATTS.
WHAT CAN A FAMILY EXPECT TO SAVE
ON A MONTHLY BILL?
A SYSTEM SIZE LIKE THIS,
WE'RE GONNA LOOK TO SAVE
ABOUT 70% TO 80%.
WE ACTUALLY FEED
INTO THE UTILITY GRID,
SO IT'LL SHOOT
BACK INTO THE GRID.
THEY'RE GONNA GET A CREDIT
ON THEIR BILL
THAT THEY'LL SEE
THE NEXT MONTH.
SO, THIS THING IS ALWAYS
EARNING THEM MONEY,
EVEN IF THEY'RE NOT HERE?
ALWAYS. ALWAYS.
GREAT THINGS
ABOUT THESE SYSTEMS --
THIS THING WILL LAST
40 YEARS.
OH, MAGIC.
Ty: HEY, PAIGE!
Paige: HEY, TY.
HOW'S IT GOING OVER HERE?
IT'S GOOD.
LOOK AT THIS.
LOOKING AWESOME.
I LOVE THE WOOD BACK THERE.
ISN'T THAT COOL?
WE DID BURNED PLYWOOD.
EASY TO DO
AND IT'S A COOL LOOK.
THIS IS A STABLE
FOR TWO HORSES.
YOU KNOW, KATHREYN --
SHE HASN'T BEEN ABLE TO
KEEP HER HORSE HERE,
AND THAT'S
WHAT SHE LOVES TO DO,
SO WE'RE GONNA BRING
THE HORSE BACK,
WE GOT A TACK ROOM THERE,
A PLACE FOR HER TO FEED,
AND IT'S GONNA BE COVERED
FROM THE HOT SUN ALL DAY.
AND WE'RE GONNA BE GETTING
SOME HAY, TOO, RIGHT?
YEAH.
ALL RIGHT. AWESOME.
LOOKS GOOD.
ED! XZIBIT!
Xzibit: YO!
HOW'S THE OLD WESTERN TOWN
COMING ALONG?
IT'S GOOD!
Ed: COMING ALONG
GREAT, BROTHER.
I TELL YOU WHAT -- WE'VE GOT
THREE SUPER-NICE BUILDINGS.
WE'VE GOT A JAILHOUSE,
WE'VE GOT A HOTEL,
AND WHAT WAS
THE LAST ONE?
GENERAL STORE.
Ed:
LITTLE ELIZABETH LOVES
EVERYTHING TO DO
WITH THE WILD WEST,
SO WE ARE GOING TO BUILD
THREE HUGE WILD-WEST PLAYHOUSES
IN HER BACKYARD.
SO, IT'S NOT JUST A FACADE?
YOU GUYS CAN GO IN?
ENCLOSED STRUCTURE,
SO THEY'LL BE ABLE TO PLAY
AND HANG OUT INSIDE.
DUDE, AWESOME.
I LOVE IT. KEEP IT UP.
MICHAEL,
HOW'S THE GREEN COMING?
CHECK IT OUT, MAN.
WE'RE ACTUALLY LAYING DOWN
THE TURF RIGHT NOW.
WE'VE GOT THREE HOLES HERE.
WE'VE GOT A SAND TRAP OVER HERE.
Michael: ONE OF SHILO'S
FAVORITE THINGS TO DO WAS GOLF,
SO I'M WORKING ON FINDING A WAY
TO GET SHILO BACK ON THE GOLF
COURSE BUT IN THE BACKYARD.
WE'RE COMING UP
WITH AN APPARATUS
THAT'LL ACTUALLY HELP HIM
BE ABLE TO HOLD THAT GOLF CLUB,
'CAUSE THAT'S BEEN
THE PROBLEM.
RIGHT.
SO, HE'LL BE ABLE TO GET OUT
HERE AND GET BACK ON THE COURSE
AND BE WITH HIS KIDS
AND THE FAMILY.
AND THEN YOU'RE PUTTING OUT
THE GREEN RIGHT NOW?
YEAH.
YOU READY FOR THIS?
LET'S ROLL IT OUT.
KEEP IT COMING. KEEP IT COMING.
A LITTLE BIT FURTHER. NICE.
HEY, GUYS.
HOW'S IT GOING IN HERE?
I BROUGHT THIS ROPE,
AND I THOUGHT
WE COULD MAKE HER NAME
ON THE WALL.
SO, YOU THINK WE CAN?
YEAH, LET'S TRY THAT.
HER NAME'S ELIZABETH,
BUT I'M THINKING
WE GO WITH HER NICKNAME,
WHICH IS LIZZIE.
SO, LIKE "I" AND THEN DO A "Z"
AND GO ALL THE WAY UP.
AND WHERE YOU GIRLS
ARE STANDING,
IT'S KIND OF
WHERE THE TEPEE'S GONNA BE,
SO WHEN SHE COMES OUT OF THE
TEPEE, SHE CAN COME UP HERE,
CHECK OUT HER NAME --
VERY GIRLY.
MICHAEL, WHAT YOU DOING?
WE GOT
THE TOUCHSCREEN HERE
THAT XZIBIT'S WORKING ON
FOR THE OFFICE, RIGHT?
SO, I SEE HE'S GONE
TO sears.com.
YEP.
AND I'M JUST ABOUT TO BUY
THAT BARBECUE RIGHT THERE.
IS THAT SWEET?
YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED?
WHAT?
SOMETHING FUN
THAT HE CAN DO WITH HIS KIDS.
I GOT A TV.
I'M MOUNTING A TV OUTSIDE,
WHICH IS GONNA BE SWEET.
BUT WHAT ELSE?
WHAT WERE YOU THINKING?
WELL, I WAS JUST THINKING
SOMETHING,
LIKE, HE COULD PLAY
WITH HIS KIDS, YOU KNOW?
LIKE, HOW ABOUT --
YOU KNOW WHAT WE NEED TO DO?
LIKE, HAVE, LIKE,
AIR HOCKEY.
PERFECT.
LET ME GO RIGHT THERE.
Michael: SHILO LOVES TO HANG OUT
WITH HIS KIDS,
AND SO WE'RE GONNA DO
AN INDOOR/OUTDOOR ROOM
THAT'LL BE CLIMATE-CONTROLLED,
FULL OF FUN AND ACTIVITIES
FOR THE FAMILY TO BE TOGETHER.
I THINK
THAT IS THE PERFECT ONE.
PERFECT. WE'RE GONNA DO
A LITTLE EXPRESS CHECKOUT. BOOM.
NOW THAT WE'VE ORDERED
EVERYTHING,
ALL WE NEED TO DO
IS GO PICK IT UP AT SEARS.
THEY'LL HAVE EVERYTHING
WAITING FOR US,
AND THEN THE ROOM IS DONE.
KIND OF AWESOME.
YEAH.
WELL, SINCE I PICKED
EVERYTHING OUT, YOU
GET TO GO PICK IT UP.
OH. OKAY.
HEY, TY.
YO.
LET ME INTRODUCE YOU
TO SOMEBODY, MAN.
THIS IS ADAM, MAN.
HE WAS ACTUALLY
IN THE HUMVEE
WHEN SHILO WAS HIT
WITH THE I.E.D.
YOU'RE ADAM?
YES, SIR.
WOW.
THANKS FOR BEING HERE, MAN.
HEY, ABSOLUTELY. I WOULDN'T
MISS THIS FOR THE WORLD.
THIS LOOKS AMAZING.
I JUST WANT TO ASK YOU,
BECAUSE, LIKE,
SHILO'S PERSONALITY, YOU CAN'T
MISS IT, YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
LIKE,
WAS HE ALWAYS THAT WAY?
SHILO HAS A KNACK
FOR PICKING PEOPLE UP.
YOU KNOW,
GOING THROUGH 18-HOUR DAYS,
NO MATTER HOW TIRED WE WERE,
SHILO COULD MAKE YOU SMILE.
HE'S JUST A REAL GOOD GUY.
HE WAS TELLING ME
THAT WHEN THE I.E.D. WENT OFF,
IT BASICALLY WENT OFF
RIGHT UNDERNEATH YOU, DIDN'T IT?
YEAH.
I GOT HURT REAL BAD,
AND THEN THEY SPLIT ME
UP THE MIDDLE A LITTLE BIT.
AAH!
YEAH.
AND THEN I GOT
SOME SHRAPNEL WOUNDS TO MY ARMS,
AND THEN I GOT A DENT
IN MY HEAD
AND SOME SKIN GRAFTS
ON THE BACK OF MY LEGS.
YOU KNOW, COMPARED TO SHILO,
I GOT LUCKY.
WOW.
BOTH OF YOU GUYS ARE EXTREMELY
LUCKY TO BE HERE TODAY.
YEAH, MAN. WELL,
WE'RE GLAD TO HAVE YOU, MAN.
HEY, I APPRECIATE IT.
WELL,
I HATE TO INTERRUPT.
WHAT WERE YOU GUYS WORKING ON?
WHAT EXACTLY IS THIS?
RIGHT NOW, YOU KNOW,
SHILO HAS ONE OF HIS THINGS
THAT HE SAYS
ALL THE TIME.
HE'S BUILDING BRIDGES
TO OPEN HEARTS.
SO, THAT'S WHAT --
WE'VE MADE THIS OUT OF METAL,
AND THESE ARE GONNA GO
AROUND THE FLAGPOLE.
OH, RIGHT ON.
ALL THE WAY UP.
ALL THE WAY UP, YEAH.
THAT'S A BEAUTIFUL IDEA.
I'M SO GLAD YOU'RE A PART
OF THIS, MAN.
ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, WELL, LOOK --
I GOT TO RUN.
I'LL MEET UP WITH YOU LATER.
VERY NICE MEETING YOU.
THANK YOU, GUYS.
WE'LL BE HERE.
ALL RIGHT, ADAM.
LET'S GET THIS STUFF
MOVING.
ALL RIGHTY.
SO, THE PARK HAS BEEN
PRETTY MUCH WELL-RECEIVED, THEN?
Hartman:
WELL BEYOND OUR EXPECTATIONS.
Ed: OUR BUILDER, GORDON,
DECIDED TO INVITE ME
DOWN TO HIS THEME PARK THAT HE
BUILT, NAMED AFTER HIS DAUGHTER.
SO, WHAT IS THE MAIN THEME,
THEN, WITH THIS PARK?
THIS IS A PARK
THAT IS ENGINEERED
WITH SPECIAL NEEDS IN MIND
BUT BUILT FOR EVERYONE.
THIS THEME PARK CATERS
FOR KIDS AND ADULTS
THAT HAVE DIFFERENT ABILITIES.
WHAT THIS PARK DOES
IS BRING DOWN THOSE BARRIERS
AND ALLOWS FOR EVERYONE
TO BE ABLE TO PLAY TOGETHER.
THIS WOULD BE REALLY COOL
IF WE COULD LET THE FAMILY
KNOW WHAT WE'RE DOING.
RIGHT.
WE NEED TO.
YEAH, LET'S DO IT.
OKAY. HERE WE GO.
HELLO, HARRIS FAMILY.
SAY HELLO, EVERYONE!
HELLO!      HELLO!
HELLO!                   HELLO!
WE'RE CHILLING OUT
HERE AT THE THEME PARK,
WHICH WAS STARTED
BY OUR BUILDER, GORDON.
THIS IS ONE
OF 26 DIFFERENT THINGS
THAT ALL KINDS OF PEOPLE
CAN GET ON.
AND WHAT I MEAN BY THAT,
NOT JUST ABLE-BODIED PEOPLE,
BUT PEOPLE WITH DIFFERENT
ABILITIES -- KIDS AND ADULTS.
WE GOT SOME GOOD NEWS FOR YOU,
AND YOUR BUILDER, GORDON,
IS GONNA TELL YOU RIGHT NOW.
BECAUSE YOU REPRESENT SO MUCH
OF WHAT THIS PLACE IS ABOUT,
WE WANT TO NAME OUR
TRANQUILITY FOUNTAIN AFTER YOU.
AND SO,
STAFF SERGEANT SHILO HARRIS,
WELCOME AND SEE YOUR NEW
TRANQUILITY FOUNTAIN.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Kat:
TO THINK OF SHILO HAVING
A TRANQUILITY FOUNTAIN
DEDICATED TO HIM,
I THINK IT'S REALLY COOL
BECAUSE TRANQUILITY IS SOMETHING
WE NEED MORE OF.
SO, MAYBE THAT'S, YOU KNOW,
JUST ONE OF THOSE WAYS
OF SAYING, "HEY.
JUST TAKE A MINUTE.
SIT WITH THE KIDS
AND JUST SIT DOWN AND ENJOY LIFE
AND BE THANKFUL
FOR WHAT YOU HAVE."
I'VE GOT TO SAY,
SHILO, HARRIS FAMILY,
THAT IS PRETTY IMPRESSIVE.
NOW, THERE IS ONE MORE SURPRISE.
IF YOU GUYS TAKE A LITTLE LOOK
BEHIND YOU,
THEN THERE SHOULD BE
A PRESENT THERE.
YOU SEE IT?
I WANT YOU GUYS
TO OPEN IT UP NOW.
OOH. WHAT IS THIS?
LIZZIE, CAN YOU SEE IT?
IT'S A CARD.
Shilo: OH, MY GOD.
[ LAUGHS ]
LET'S COMPARE.
GERM PARTY!
EWW!
NOW THE COLGATE TOTAL MOUTH.
NICE!
[ Female Announcer ]
COLGATE TOTAL FIGHTS 90%
MORE PLAQUE GERMS.
I'M IN.
[ Female Announcer ]
COLGATE TOTAL.
LESS GERMS. HEALTHIER MOUTH.
CAN YOUR MOISTURIZER DO THAT?
[ Female Announcer ]
DERMATOLOGIST RECOMMENDED
Aveeno HAS AN OAT FORMULA,
NOW PROVEN
TO BUILD A MOISTURE RESERVE,
SO SKIN CAN REPLENISH ITSELF.
THAT'S HEALTHY SKIN FOR LIFE.
ONLY FROM Aveeno.
SOMETHING THIS DELICIOUS
COULD ONLY COME FROM NATURE.
NEW NECTRESSE.
THE 100% NATURAL
NO-CALORIE SWEETENER
MADE FROM THE GOODNESS
OF FRUIT.
NEW NECTRESSE.
SWEETNESS NATURALLY.
LET'S COMPARE.
GERM PARTY!
EWW!
NOW THE COLGATE TOTAL MOUTH.
NICE!
[ Female Announcer ]
COLGATE TOTAL FIGHTS 90%
MORE PLAQUE GERMS.
I'M IN.
[ Female Announcer ]
COLGATE TOTAL.
LESS GERMS. HEALTHIER MOUTH.
IF YOU GUYS TAKE A LITTLE LOOK
BEHIND YOU,
THEN THERE SHOULD BE
A PRESENT THERE.
YOU SEE IT?
I WANT YOU GUYS
TO OPEN IT UP NOW.
OOH. WHAT IS THIS?
LIZZIE, CAN YOU SEE IT?
IT'S A CARD.
"MORTGAGE NOTE PAID IN FULL."
YOU HAVE MORE MORTGAGE!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
MERRY, MERRY CHRISTMAS.
Kat: KNOWING THAT I DON'T HAVE
TO MAKE THAT PAYMENT EVERY MONTH
IS AN AMAZING FEELING.
BEING ABLE TO TRAVEL
AND GO TALK TO WOUNDED WARRIORS
AND THEIR FAMILIES
WILL BE SOMETHING
THAT WE'RE ABLE TO DO
A LOT MORE FREQUENTLY NOW
BECAUSE WE DON'T HAVE
THAT MONTHLY MORTGAGE PAYMENT.
WE'LL SEE YOU
IN A COUPLE OF DAYS.
BYE!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Woman: MERRY CHRISTMAS!
TELL YOU WHAT --
FROM UP HERE, YOU CAN REALLY SEE
JUST HOW INCREDIBLE
THIS THING REALLY IS.
RIGHT HERE ON THE FRONT,
THE LANDSCAPING,
SHOWING OFF THE FLAG,
AND IN THE BACKYARD,
YOU CAN SEE THE NEW WESTERN TOWN
THAT'S GONNA BE SO INCREDIBLE
FOR THE FAMILY AND THE KIDS
TO BE ABLE TO HAVE FUN,
AND, OF COURSE,
I LOVE THE PUTTING GREEN.
HE'S NOW GONNA HAVE
AIR-FILTRATION SYSTEMS,
GIVE HIM CLEAN AIR.
HE'S GONNA HAVE
TEMPERATURE CONTROL
SO WHEN HE GETS HOT,
HE CAN ACTUALLY COOL DOWN.
FOR ALL THAT HE'S GIVEN
TO THIS COUNTRY,
NOW THIS COMMUNITY
IS GIVING BACK.
Paige: AND LET'S
TAKE THIS BACK ONE
AND PUT IT ON TOP OF THERE
IF WE CAN.
OH. AND HERE COMES
OUR VERY SPECIAL GUEST.
IS THIS BRANDY?
Glenda: THIS IS BRANDY.
THIS IS KATHREYN'S HORSE.
KATHREYN HASN'T BEEN ABLE TO BE
WITH HER HORSE FOR MANY YEARS.
YOU KNOW,
SHE'S BEEN TAKING CARE OF SHILO,
BUT SHE LOST SIGHT
OF WHAT SHE REALLY LOVES TO DO.
I'M GLENDA...
GLENDA?
KATHREYN'S AUNT.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
I HAVE A PICTURE OF KATHREYN
WHEN SHE WAS ABOUT 16.
THIS REALLY
IS GONNA BE A PLACE
THAT KATHREYN
CAN FIND HERSELF AGAIN
AND REALLY DO THE THINGS
THAT SHE ENJOYS DOING.
SO, WHAT DO YOU THINK? DO YOU
LIKE YOUR NEW HOME, BRANDY?
I THINK SHE'S HAPPY.
Xzibit: HEY, TY!
WE GOT THE FLAGPOLE COMING IN.
EXCELLENT. BRING IT RIGHT OVER
HERE. WE'RE READY TO GO.
LET'S SET IT DOWN RIGHT HERE
FOR A SECOND, GUYS.
ALL RIGHT.
Man: LINE IT RIGHT UP.
OKAY. SO, THIS WAS --
THIS IS SHILO'S ORIGINAL FLAG
THEY FLY IN THE FRONT YARD.
EXACTLY. AND THIS HAS
A LOT OF SENTIMENTAL VALUE.
HIS BEST FRIEND
PUT THAT IN THERE FOR HIM.
EXACTLY. AND SO
THIS IS OUR NEW POLE.
I MEAN, THIS IS NICE.
WHERE'D YOU GET THIS?
MY MAN RIGHT HERE --
HE DONATED IT.
OH, REALLY?
YOU DONATED THIS?
YES, SIR.
I'VE ALWAYS DONE STUFF TO
HELP OUT OUR WOUNDED WARRIORS,
AND I GO TO BASIC TRAINING
FOR THE NAVY
ON VALENTINE'S DAY, SO I WANTED
TO DO SOMETHING BEFORE I LEFT.
NO KIDDING?
AFTER MEETING SHILO AND ALL
THESE OTHER WOUNDED WARRIORS,
YOU REALIZE THAT THIS IS
A FAMILY THAT MAKES SACRIFICES
THAT A LOT OF US
REALLY TAKE FOR GRANTED,
AND THIS WEEK,
IT'S ABOUT GIVING BACK TO THEM
AND RECEIVING THE HONOR OF BEING
ABLE TO ACTUALLY HELP THEM.
NICE JOB, FELLAS.
THANK YOU.
ALL RIGHT.
Man: SEE YOU GUYS.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Ty:
THIS WEEK, WE WANTED TO DO WHAT
WE COULD FOR WOUNDED WARRIORS,
GIVING THEM THE RESPECT AND THE
HONOR THAT THEY TRULY DESERVE.
I JUST WANT TO SAY
IT IS SO AWESOME
TO SEE ALL OF YOU GUYS
COMING OUT HERE
TO SUPPORT OUR MEN AND WOMEN
SERVING AND OUR TROOPS.
I TELL YOU WHAT, YOU CAN SEE
WHY THEY CALL SAN ANTONIO
"MILITARY CITY, U.S.A."
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
OKAY, SO, RIGHT NOW, THE HARRIS
FAMILY -- THEY'RE ON VACATION.
I KNOW
THAT THEY WOULD LOVE TO KNOW
WHAT IS GOING ON HERE RIGHT NOW.
SO, WHAT DO YOU SAY WE LET THEM
KNOW WHAT'S HAPPENING, YEAH?
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
HELLO, HARRIS FAMILY!
HI, TY!
HI, TY!                  HI, TY!
RIGHT NOW, WE'RE HERE AT THE
FAMOUS SAN ANTONIO RIVER WALK,
WHERE THEY HOLD
THEIR ANNUAL RIVERBOAT PARADE.
AND WE FIGURE
WHAT BETTER PLACE TO PAY TRIBUTE
TO OUR SERVICEMEN AND -WOMEN
WHO ARE COMING HOME?
SO, WE DECIDED TO THROW
A RED, WHITE, AND BLUE
CHRISTMAS PARADE!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
CHECK THIS OUT.
WOW.
OH, WOW.
THAT'S PRETTY.
OH, MY FAVORITE --
THE MARIACHIS.
THE RED, WHITE, AND BLUE
CHRISTMAS PARADE
ON THE RIVER WALK
WAS JUST A SIGHT TO SEE.
IT WAS SO BEAUTIFUL, AND
THE BOATS AND THE MARIACHIS --
IT MADE THE HOLIDAYS
VERY SPECIAL.
NOW, THIS IS WHAT YOU CALL
A BIG MOMENT, BECAUSE THIS WEEK,
WE FOLLOWED
IN THE FAMILY'S FOOTSTEPS
AND WE RAISED A LOT OF MONEY,
AND I CAN'T BELIEVE I'M EVEN
GONNA TELL YOU THIS NUMBER,
BECAUSE IT'S A GOOD ONE.
WE HAVE RAISED THIS WEEK...
$1.1 MILLION!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THE $1.1 MILLION THAT WAS RAISED
AND SEEING ALL THESE THOUSANDS
OF PEOPLE COMING TOGETHER
TO SAY, "THANK YOU"
AND "WE LOVE YOU" --
THAT'S TRULY, TRULY AMAZING.
SO, WE'VE TEAMED UP THIS WEEK
WITH AN ORGANIZATION
CALLED HELPING A HERO, AND
THEY DO PRETTY MUCH WHAT WE DO.
THEY BUILD ACCESSIBLE HOMES
FOR SOLDIERS THAT NEED THEM.
NOW, WITH THE MONEY
WE'VE RAISED THIS WEEK,
WE'RE ALREADY BEGINNING
TO CHANGE LIVES.
MEREDITH ILER,
WHY DON'T YOU COME UP HERE?
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Man:
WE LOVE YOU, MEREDITH!
SO, THIS WEEK, WE CAN START
BUILDING BRAND-NEW HOMES
THAT ARE ACCESSIBLE
FOR WOUNDED WARRIORS
FOR 10 FAMILIES RIGHT HERE.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
GOOD.
I'M GONNA START BY INVITING
CAPTAIN SAM BROWN,
YOUR BEAUTIFUL WIFE.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THAT'S GREAT.
WE'RE JUST SO EXCITED
THAT WE'RE GONNA BE ABLE
TO BUILD YOU A HOME
THAT HAS ALL YOU NEED
TO BE HEALTHY
FOR A LONG, LONG, LONG TIME.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THANK YOU, MEREDITH. WE'RE NOT
PROMISED ANOTHER DAY IN LIFE.
WE'RE NOT EVEN PROMISED
THE HEALTH THAT WE LOST.
BUT TODAY,
TO BE ABLE TO BE PROMISED
A PLACE TO RAISE A FAMILY
WITH MEMORIES AND A FUTURE
AND THE RIPPLE EFFECTS
THAT HAPPEN FROM THAT,
IT'S UNIMAGINABLE.
HELPING A HERO IS DEDICATED
TO BUILDING HOMES FOR VETERANS,
AND THAT MEANS SO MUCH TO THESE
WARRIORS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
CORPORAL RONNY PORTA.
I MEAN,
THIS IS AN AMAZING OPPORTUNITY
FOR THEM TO START OVER
IN AN ENVIRONMENT THAT'S
COMFORTABLE, FITTED FOR THEM.
THAT'S AMAZING.
[ APPLAUSE ]
ALEX DEL RIO, HIS BEAUTIFUL
WIFE, VANESSA. WHOO!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Paige:
BEING SURROUNDED BY ALL THESE
VETERANS AND THEIR FAMILIES
WAS REALLY EYE-OPENING.
THEY'RE MISSING LIMBS.
THEY'VE BEEN BURNED OVER
MOST OF THEIR BODY.
THEY'VE HAD THESE TRAGIC THINGS
HAPPEN TO THEM,
BUT THEY SAY, "YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'D DO IT ALL OVER AGAIN."
THAT'S SOME SERIOUS DEDICATION
AND SOME SERIOUS PATRIOTISM
THAT MAKES ME PROUD
TO SHARE A COUNTRY WITH THEM.
Man: YEAH!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THIS WEEK, WE GOT TO BE
A TINY, LITTLE PART
OF MAKING THEIR LIVES BETTER.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
SERGEANT KENDRA COLEMAN
AND HER FIANCé, ANTHONY GARZA.
[ Voice breaking ] YOU KNOW,
Y'ALL KEEP THANKING US,
BUT IN REALITY,
WE NEED TO THANK YOU
BECAUSE NONE OF THIS
WOULD BE POSSIBLE
IF IT WASN'T FOR YOUR SUPPORT.
YOU KNOW, AMERICA --
IT'S NOT JUST THE SOLDIERS.
WE'RE ALL A TEAM.
SO, THANK YOU FOR YOUR SUPPORT.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Ty:
SO, WE FIGURED
WHAT BETTER WAY TO CAP OFF
THIS INCREDIBLE EVENING
THAN WITH A BEAUTIFUL SONG FROM
SINGER-SONGWRITER LEE GREENWOOD?
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
WHOO!
♪ I'D THANK MY LUCKY STARS
♪ TO BE LIVIN' HERE TODAY
♪ 'CAUSE THE FLAG
STILL STANDS FOR FREEDOM ♪
♪ AND THEY CAN'T
TAKE THAT AWAY ♪
♪ AND I'M PROUD TO BE
AN AMERICAN ♪
♪ WHERE AT LEAST
I KNOW I'M FREE ♪
♪ AND I WON'T FORGET
THE MEN WHO DIED ♪
♪ AND GAVE THAT RIGHT TO ME
Ty:
IT WAS A BIG NIGHT --
NOT ONLY BUILDING A HOME
FOR SOMEONE LIKE SHILO,
WHO INSPIRES OTHER SOLDIERS,
BUT TO SURPRISE
SOME OF THESE WOUNDED WARRIORS
BY GIVING THEM HOMES
THAT'S ACCESSIBLE.
I THINK THAT'S AMAZING,
ALLOWING THEM
TO BE ABLE TO FINALLY
NOT HAVE TO GO UP STAIRS,
TO BE ABLE TO MAKE THEIR LIFE
JUST A LITTLE BIT EASIER
AFTER MAKING SACRIFICES
FOR OUR COUNTRY.
THIS REALLY IS A WEEK
THAT WE CAN ALL BE PROUD OF.
♪ 'CAUSE THERE AIN'T NO DOUBT
I LOVE THIS LAND ♪
♪ GOD BLESS THE U.S.A.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THAT WAS AWESOME.
IT WAS.
THANK YOU, LEE!
HARRIS FAMILY,
HAVE A GREAT TIME ON VACATION!
WE'LL SEE YOU
WHEN YOU GET BACK!
SAY BYE, EVERYBODY!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
[ CROWD CHANTING
"U.S.A.! U.S.A.!" ]
Paige:
THIS IS SO COOL.
THIS IS AN INFRARED CAMERA,
SO INSTEAD OF SEEING, YOU KNOW,
THE NORMAL COLOR,
WE'RE GONNA SEE HEAT.
LOOK AT THIS.
THEY ARE --
83°.
WOW.
SO, HOW CAN WE USE THIS TO BEST
HELP SHILO AND HIS NEEDS?
SO, FOR EXAMPLE,
WHAT WE WOULD LOOK FOR HERE,
WE'RE LOOKING AT
A COLD-AIR VENT,
AND WE WANT TO HAVE
EQUAL DISTRIBUTION OF
THE AIR COMING OUT,
AND IN THIS CASE, IF YOU
LOOK AT THE AIR PATTERN...
UH-HUH.
...YOU CAN SEE THAT IT'S COLDER
'CAUSE IT'S DARKER.
SO, WE COULD CORRECT THAT BY
MOVING THE LOUVERS ON THE VENT
TO MAKE SURE WE HAVE
EQUAL DISTRIBUTION OF AIR.
OKAY. VERY COOL.
THIS IS
A SMOKE GENERATOR.
OH.
WE USE THIS
FOR HOSPITAL INSTALLATIONS.
Xzibit:
LET'S SEE HOW IT WORKS.
Paige: THE AIR-FILTRATION SYSTEM
IS HOSPITAL-GRADE,
AND FOR SOMEONE LIKE SHILO,
WHO CAN'T REGULATE
AND CAN'T FIGHT THAT DUST
THAT ENTERS HIS LUNGS,
THIS IS A PERFECT SYSTEM
FOR HIM.
YOU'RE GENERATING,
BASICALLY, THE POLLUTION,
AND WE WANT TO SEE IF THIS
GOES AWAY IN THE HOUSE.
WE'RE GONNA MAKE SURE
THAT ALL THE AIR THAT'S IN
THIS AREA IS BEING RETURNED
AND IT'S GOING THROUGH
A HYPER-HEPA FILTRATION SYSTEM,
REMOVING 90% TO 98%
OF ALL OF THE PARTICLES
THAT ARE IN THE AIR.
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT SHILO NEEDS.
MISSION ACCOMPLISHED.
YES! I LOVE IT!
ED, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
HOW YOU DOING, BRO?
WHAT'S UP, BRO?
BRO, THIS IS COMING TOGETHER
REAL NICE. I TELL YOU WHAT.
MAN, COMING TOGETHER?
IT'S TOGETHER.
IT'S UNBELIEVABLE, HUH?
YEAH, IT IS, MAN.
BACK OF THE HOUSE LOOKING
BEAUTIFUL, GOLF COURSE.
TO BE HONEST, THOUGH,
THE BEST PART OF THIS
WHOLE YARD IS THIS.
I'M TELLING YOU, MAN --
THE KIDS, YOU KNOW,
WE STARTED OUT WITH
A TRAMPOLINE AND SOME DIRT,
AND NOW WE GOT A REAL
WESTERN TOWN IN THE BACKYARD.
I THINK
IT'S FAIR TO SAY, BRO,
THAT L.A. AND LONDON
CAN COME TOGETHER AND
MAKE A WESTERN TOWN.
I'M TELLING YOU, MAN.
WE DID THAT.
GOOD JOB, BUDDY.
ALL RIGHT. COOL.
LET'S GET IT.
PERFECT TOUCH TO A COWGIRL ROOM.
GOT TO HAVE HORSES.
Man: ONE, TWO, THREE.
Xzibit: SHILO'S GONNA LOVE
SEEING THIS BENCH
WITH HIS SQUADRON
AND HIS RANK ON IT.
ISN'T THAT GORGEOUS?
YEAH, IT IS.
ALL RIGHT.
LAST CABOOSE GOING ON.
[ WHISTLE BLOWS ]
BEAUTIFUL.
Ty: SO, LOOK --
I KNOW WE STILL GOT
A LITTLE BIT OF WORK TO DO
ON THE LANDSCAPING,
BUT THE HOUSE --
WE'RE READY
TO MOVE IN FURNITURE.
WE'RE READY TO GO.
LET'S MOVE IN
SOME FURNITURE!
Ty: THIS REALLY IS A WEEK
THAT WE CAN ALL BE PROUD OF.
BUILDING A HOME
FOR SOMEONE LIKE SHILO,
WHO INSPIRES OTHER WOUNDED
WARRIORS, LIFTS YOUR SPIRITS,
AND, AT THE SAME TIME,
IT MAKES YOU REALLY UNDERSTAND
HOW DIFFICULT IT CAN BE
FOR THESE GUYS.
ARE YOU OKAY WITH THAT?
DO YOU NEED ANY HELP WITH THAT?
I'M SO HONORED
THAT WE CAN GIVE BACK
TO A HERO WHO HAS GIVEN SO MUCH.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
[ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
HELLO?
HEY, KAT.
IT'S TY.
HEY, TY.
HOW YOU DOING?
So, here's the thing.
WE'VE GOT ONE MORE STOP
BEFORE WE BRING YOU GUYS HOME.
In fact, I think it's something
you're really gonna like.
OKAY.
YOU GUYS ARE GONNA GET TO SEE
YOUR FRIEND J.R. MARTINEZ.
You guys are gonna do
some public speaking together.
SOUND LIKE A COOL THING?
Anything
I get to do with him
IS GONNA BE AWESOME --
I KNOW IT WILL BE.
WELL, GUYS, HAVE FUN,
AND WE'LL SEE YOU WHEN
YOU GET BACK, OKAY?
SOUNDS GREAT.
J.R.:
HEY. WHAT'S UP, MAN?
HOW YOU DOING?
IT'S GOOD TO SEE YOU.
SHILO AND I HAVE KNOWN EACH
OTHER FOR A COUPLE OF YEARS NOW,
AND I'VE GOTTEN TO KNOW HIM.
HE'S ALWAYS TALKING ABOUT
HIS WIFE AND HIS CHILDREN.
HE'S A FAMILY MAN.
HE'S SUCH AN INSPIRATION.
WHAT WE WERE ABLE
TO DO TODAY
IS SET UP A VISIT
WITH SOME OF THE PATIENTS,
SOME OF THE KIDS
THAT ARE HERE AT THE HOSPITAL,
AND ALSO SOME OF THE TROOPS
AND GIVE AN OPPORTUNITY
WHERE ME AND YOU CAN ACTUALLY
GO IN THERE TOGETHER,
JUST KIND OF GIVE THEM,
YOU KNOW,
THE INSPIRATION
THAT WAS GIVEN TO US.
SOUND GOOD?
ABSOLUTELY.
ALL RIGHT, MAN.
WELL, LET'S GET IN THERE.
Shilo:
THE FIRST TIME I MET J.R.,
IT WAS SHORTLY AFTER
I HAD BEEN INJURED.
HE REALLY GAVE ME HOPE
THAT I WAS GONNA GET BETTER.
MY CAREER PATH RIGHT NOW
IS BEING A MOTIVATIONAL SPEAKER,
SO GETTING TO ACTUALLY DO THAT
WITH J.R.,
THE PERSON THAT INSPIRED ME --
I MEAN, WOW.
HOW COOL IS THAT?
I WANT TO INTRODUCE
MY FRIEND SHILO HARRIS,
WHO IS GONNA SHARE A FEW WORDS
WITH YOU GUYS.
THERE YOU GO, MAN.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
SO, I DON'T KNOW
IF Y'ALL NOTICED OR NOT,
BUT I'M WEARING MY SPOCK EARS
FOR Y'ALL TODAY.
DID Y'ALL NOTICE THOSE?
I LIKE TO THINK THAT I'M
PRETTY DASHINGLY HANDSOME.
NOT AS GOOD-LOOKING AS J.R.,
BUT, YOU KNOW...
LIKE J.R., I WAS BURNT
ON MY UPPER TORSO,
AND IT WAS ABOUT
35% OF MY BODY,
BUT I HONESTLY FEEL LIKE
I'M TRULY BLESSED.
THE GLASSES THAT I WAS WEARING
ACTUALLY SAVED MY EYES.
IF I HAD LOST MY SIGHT,
I WOULDN'T HAVE BEEN ABLE
TO SEE MY SON BORN.
AND I WOULDN'T BE ABLE TO SEE
MY BEAUTIFUL DAUGHTER,
SO I FEEL VERY FORTUNATE.
AND THAT'S SOMETHING
THAT I LIKE TO TELL PEOPLE.
BE SURE AND COUNT YOUR BLESSINGS
FOR WHAT YOU DO HAVE.
WHAT I'VE BEEN ABLE TO DO
IS JUST SHOW THE WORLD
THAT IT DOESN'T MATTER WHAT
YOU LOOK LIKE ON THE OUTSIDE.
IT DOESN'T MATTER
HOW DIFFERENT YOU ARE.
WHAT MATTERS IS WHO YOU ARE
IN YOUR HEART, YOU KNOW?
WHAT MATTERS IS, YOU
KNOW, WHAT'S DEEPER
THAN A THIRD-DEGREE BURN
THAT THE FIRE COULDN'T REACH,
YOU KNOW?
AND WE'RE STILL
THE SAME PEOPLE.
Shilo: SOME OF THOSE PEOPLE
HAVE SUFFERED,
BEEN THROUGH SURGERIES,
AND EXPERIENCING THINGS
THAT IS JUST ROUGH.
IT WAS TOUGH FOR ME TO SAY,
"OKAY.
HOW AM I GONNA TALK TO THEM?"
GETTING TO SEE J.R. IN ACTION, I
REALIZED YOU JUST TALK TO THEM.
YOU TELL YOUR STORY,
BE LIGHTHEARTED, LISTEN TO THEM.
MAYBE I WAS HERE
TO HELP INSPIRE THEM,
BUT, HONESTLY, I THINK IT MIGHT
HAVE BEEN THE OTHER WAY AROUND,
'CAUSE THEY INSPIRED ME.
AS MUCH AS WE ENJOY
HEARING SHILO'S STORY,
WE ACTUALLY
HAVE TO LET THEM GO
BECAUSE THEY HAVE A BIG NIGHT
AHEAD OF THEM.
THEY'RE ACTUALLY
GETTING READY
TO SEE THEIR HOUSE
FOR THE VERY FIRST TIME.
SO, LET'S GIVE
A BIG ROUND OF APPLAUSE
AS THEY GO AHEAD
AND GO TO SEE THAT HOME.
SO, THANK YOU.
GO SEE THAT HOME, MAN.
ALL RIGHT.
GO SEE THAT HOME.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
ALL RIGHT, PEOPLE!
WE FINISHED THE HOUSE!
HEY, SANTA,
LET'S BRING THEM HOME!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
AWW!
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
SHILO!
WELCOME HOME, HARRIS FAMILY!
GLEN! LIZZIE!
KATHREYN!
Kat:
SEEING ALL THOSE PEOPLE
PUTS YOU
IN A SPEECHLESS POSITION.
YOU KNOW, A LOT OF THOSE FOLKS
WERE AWAY FROM THEIR FAMILIES
TO DO SOMETHING FOR MY FAMILY.
THEY DIDN'T HAVE TO DO THAT.
THIS OPPORTUNITY
THAT'S BEEN PUT IN FRONT OF US
AND THIS WONDERFUL GIFT
ISN'T JUST ABOUT US.
IT'S ABOUT THE COMMUNITY
THAT WE REPRESENT
AND THE LOVE THAT AMERICA HAS
FOR OUR WARRIORS
AND VETERAN COMMUNITY.
I CANNOT THANK Y'ALL ENOUGH
FOR SHOWING UP OUT HERE TODAY
AND SHOWING YOUR LOVE
FOR OUR GREAT NATION
AND OUR HEROES THAT SERVE
EACH AND EVERY DAY.
THANK YOU.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
SO, WE ARE SO EXCITED TO SHOW
YOU WHAT'S BEHIND THIS BUS.
ARE YOU GUYS
READY TO SHOW THEM?
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
All: MOVE THAT BUS!
MOVE THAT BUS!
YOU GUYS KNOW WHAT TO SAY.
SAY IT WITH ME.
BUS DRIVER, MOVE THAT BUS!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
WOW!
Shilo:
WHEN THAT BUS FINALLY MOVED,
I WAS REALLY TRYING HARD
TO KEEP IT TOGETHER.
THE HOUSE THAT WE LIVED IN
BEFORE WASN'T IN TERRIBLE SHAPE.
IT WAS JUST UNFORTUNATE
THAT IT DIDN'T WORK FOR US.
THIS NEW HOME REPRESENTS HOPE,
AND I LOVE IT.
THEY MADE THE HOUSE TO HELP ME.
I WANTED THIS TO ALSO BE
FOR ALL OF US.
WE'RE GONNA DO GREAT.
THIS HOUSE
IS A GREAT OPPORTUNITY
FOR US TO HAVE A FRESH START.
WOW.
I'M BLOWN AWAY.
WHEW. MY CHEST JUST FEELS LIKE
IT'S FIXING TO BURST.
LOOK AT YOUR FLAGPOLE
OVER THERE.
Ty:
THIS IS A BRAND-NEW FLAGPOLE
THAT ACTUALLY WAS DONATED
BY SERVICEMEN.
THAT IS AMAZING.
YOU SEE YOUR QUOTE
OVER THERE?
"BUILDING BRIDGES
TO OPEN HEARTS."
THANK YOU.
THIS WEEK,
WE GOT THE OPPORTUNITY
TO MEET A LOT
OF WOUNDED WARRIORS.
WHEN YOU WERE DOING YOUR TOUR,
YOU WERE HIT BY AN I.E.D.
I KNOW THERE'S ONLY ONE OTHER
PERSON THAT SURVIVED THAT.
ADAM, COME ON OUT HERE.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Shilo: I WANTED TO CRY
WHEN I SEEN ADAM.
HE WAS THERE ON MY WORST DAY,
AND, BY GOLLY,
HE SHOULD DADGUM SURE BE THERE
ON MY BEST DAY.
AND THIS WAS BY FAR
ONE OF THE BEST DAYS EVER.
YOU GUYS
LOVE THE HOUSE?
YES.
PLEASE GIVE A GUY
WHO'S REALLY BEEN
LEADING THE CHARGE THIS WEEK,
AND, OF COURSE, I'M TALKING
ABOUT OUR BUILDER,
GORDON HARTMAN,
AND HIS WHOLE CREW.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Gordon:
DURING THE CHRISTMAS SEASON,
THERE ARE A LOT OF PEOPLE
WHO ARE DEFENDING THIS COUNTRY
AND HAVING TO PUT FAMILY
AND OTHER PRIORITIES ASIDE
TO DO THAT.
Y'ALL ARE
A TRUE AMERICAN HERO FAMILY,
AND WE THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR THIS OPPORTUNITY.
IN BUILDING THIS HOME,
THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE
DID THE SAME THING
TO MAKE THAT HAPPEN.
THAT'S THEIR GIFT
TO A WOUNDED WARRIOR,
TO SAY THAT,
"WE KNOW IT'S TOUGH,
"BUT WE'RE GONNA GET THROUGH IT,
AND BY GETTING THROUGH IT,
WE'RE GONNA BE STRONGER."
I'D LIKE TO ASK DR. PORTER
TO COME FORWARD.
THERE'S A LITTLE SOMETHING EXTRA
HERE, AS WELL.
Kat: OH, WOW.
THE UNIVERSITY
OF THE INCARNATE WORD,
WITH THIS CERTIFICATE,
IS GIVING YOU
TWO $50,000 COLLEGE SCHOLARSHIPS
FOR YOUR TWO CHILDREN.
CONGRATULATIONS.
Dr. Porter:
THANK YOU FOR YOUR SERVICE.
Ty:
YOU'RE GOING TO COLLEGE!
Kat:
KNOWING THAT LIZZIE AND GLEN
HAVE THESE SCHOLARSHIPS
TO INCARNATE WORD
KIND OF TAKES A STRESS OFF.
IT'S AMAZING
AND WONDERFUL AND...
WOW.
ON BEHALF
OF EVERYONE INVOLVED,
I'D LIKE TO GIVE YOU
THE KEYS TO YOUR NEW HOME.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
DAD!
[ ALL CHANTING
"U.S.A.! U.S.A.!" ]
Shilo: YOU KNOW, GETTING TO SEE
THOSE FIREWORKS GO OFF,
IT WAS AMAZING.
NOT A WHOLE LOT HAPPENS LIKE
THAT OUT IN SMALLTOWN, U.S.A.
Y'ALL BROUGHT SOMETHING
VERY SPECIAL TO WILSON COUNTY
THAT THEY'LL NEVER FORGET.
SO, THANK YOU FOR THAT.
[ CHANTING CONTINUES ]
SO, HARRIS FAMILY, I'VE BEEN
WAITING TO SAY THIS ALL WEEK.
GUYS,
GO CHECK OUT YOUR HOUSE!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
LET'S COMPARE.
GERM PARTY!
EWW!
NOW THE COLGATE TOTAL MOUTH.
NICE!
[ Female Announcer ]
COLGATE TOTAL FIGHTS 90%
MORE PLAQUE GERMS.
I'M IN.
[ Female Announcer ]
COLGATE TOTAL.
LESS GERMS. HEALTHIER MOUTH.
LET'S COMPARE.
GERM PARTY!
EWW!
NOW THE COLGATE TOTAL MOUTH.
NICE!
[ Female Announcer ]
COLGATE TOTAL FIGHTS 90%
MORE PLAQUE GERMS.
I'M IN.
[ Female Announcer ]
COLGATE TOTAL.
LESS GERMS. HEALTHIER MOUTH.
GUYS,
GO CHECK OUT YOUR HOUSE!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Kat:
LOOK UP. OH, WOW.
OH, MAN!
HOLY COW!
OH, WOW.
WALKING IN THE FRONT DOOR
FOR THE FIRST TIME,
THAT'S WHEN YOU
REALLY START TAKING IT IN,
AND YOU'RE FEELING
THAT FLOOD OF LOVE.
IT WAS OVERWHELMING
FOR ALL OF US.
I'M SCARED
I'M GONNA BREAK SOMETHING.
[ BOTH LAUGH ]
OHH.
UH-OH. GLEN.
THERE ARE STOCKING --
OR "BOOT" STOCKINGS.
I LIKE THAT.
[ LAUGHS ]
IT WAS JUST LIKE,
"IS THIS REALLY HAPPENING?
WOW. THIS IS REALLY MINE."
IT WAS REALLY, REALLY AMAZING.
SO, HARRIS FAMILY, WHAT DO YOU
THINK OF YOUR BRAND-NEW HOME?
I FEEL LIKE
IT'S SOMEBODY ELSE'S HOUSE.
I MEAN,
THIS THING IS AMAZING.
DUDE, THIS IS SO YOUR HOUSE
THAT IT'S ACTUALLY
CUSTOM-DESIGNED
JUST FOR YOUR NEEDS.
SO, I KNOW IN YOUR OLD HOUSE,
YOU HAD REAL WORRIES
ABOUT REGULATING
YOUR TEMPERATURE
BUT ALSO WITH THE AIR QUALITY
THAT WAS IN YOUR HOUSE.
WELL, I CAN TELL YOU, THIS HOUSE
IS INCREDIBLY INSULATED.
IT ALLOWS YOU TO ALSO CONTROL
YOUR TEMPERATURE.
BUT YOU'VE ALSO GOT
A STATE-OF-THE-ART
AIR-FILTRATION SYSTEM,
SO THE AIR
YOU'RE BREATHING RIGHT NOW
IS THE SAME QUALITY
THAT YOU FIND IN HOSPITALS.
OH, WOW.
HE WOULD ALWAYS TALK ABOUT
HE COULD FEEL HIS LUNGS HURTING.
IT'D BE PAINFUL,
AND I FEEL LIKE, YOU KNOW,
THE NEW HOUSE, WITH
THE FILTRATION THAT'S IN IT,
SHILO WILL BE ABLE
TO BREATHE EASIER.
HE'LL FEEL BETTER.
HIS LUNGS WON'T HURT.
HOPEFULLY, IT WON'T BE SUCH
A HARD THING FOR HIM TO DO NOW.
YOU NOW HAVE A STATE-OF-THE-ART
AIR-PURIFICATION SYSTEM,
SO NOT ONLY DOES THIS
FILTER THE AIR, IT PURIFIES IT.
SO, IT TAKES
ALL THE PARTICLES,
ALL THE IMPURITIES
OUT OF THE AIR.
WOW.
IT REALLY IS PHENOMENAL.
AND I KNOW
THE INJURIES THAT YOU HAD,
NOT ONLY ON THE EXTERIOR,
BUT IT'S ALSO THE INTERIOR --
YOU'RE GONNA BE ABLE TO BREATHE
PURE, CLEAN AIR.
Shilo: THERE WAS JUST A LOT OF
CHALLENGES WITH THE UNIT BEFORE.
THIS...
[CHUCKLES] WOW.
I CAN'T EVEN BEGIN TO DESCRIBE
HOW HAPPY I AM ABOUT IT.
FROM THE MOMENT
YOU WALK THROUGH THAT DOOR,
YOU CAN TELL
THAT THE AIR IS, LIKE,
A THOUSAND TIMES BETTER
THAN IT EVER WAS.
NOW, THIS
IS A REALLY COOL PROJECT
WE'VE BEEN WORKING ON
ALL WEEK.
NOW, THIS IS YOUR COFFEE TABLE,
BUT, AS YOU CAN SEE,
THESE ARE THE COINS THAT I KNOW
MEAN A LOT TO YOU.
AND SO THIS HAS BEEN CUSTOM-MADE
TO SHOWCASE THEM.
THIS IS PERFECT.
THIS IS EXACTLY WHAT I WANT,
SO Y'ALL HIT IT ON THE HEAD.
I MEAN, THIS IS PERFECT.
OKAY. SO, YOU GUYS LIKE
WHAT YOU'VE SEEN SO FAR?
SO FAR.
ABSOLUTELY.
WELL, HERE'S THE THING.
THERE'S A LOT MORE HOUSE TO SEE.
YOU GUYS WANT TO SEE
SOME MORE HOUSE?
YEAH!
WELL, THEN, GO CHECK OUT
THE REST OF YOUR HOUSE!
LET'S GO!
[ TY CHUCKLES ]
OH, MY GOSH!
THIS IS AWESOME!
AWESOME, AWESOME, AWESOME!
WHEN I WALKED INTO MY ROOM,
I WAS ABOUT TO CRY.
BUT I HELD ALL OF THAT IN,
AND I SAID, "OH, MY GOSH.
THIS IS SO CUTE AND PRETTY."
THESE ARE REALLY COOL.
IT WAS FILLED WITH HORSES,
BOOTS ON THE SIDE OF MY BED,
BIG CLOSET FILLED
WITH NEW CLOTHES, PURSES.
HI!
DO YOU LIKE YOUR ROOM?
YES, I DO!
YES?
YOU LIKE?
SO, WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF YOUR BED?
IT'S COOL.
Paige: NO ONE ELSE
IS GONNA HAVE A BED LIKE THIS.
IT'S CUSTOM-MADE --
EVEN THE MATTRESS.
MY ROOM HAS EVERYTHING
THAT A COWGIRL NEEDS.
THIS IS SO AWESOME.
AWESOME!
TRAIN!
A TRAIN!
THOSE ARE TRAIN!
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
COME IN!
♪ DUN-DA-DA-LA-DA
DUN-DUN-DA! ♪
HOW YOU DOING, BUDDY?
GOOD.
YOU LIKE THIS?
TRAIN.
THIS IS JUST
THE BESTEST!
LITTLE GLEN WAS JUST --
HE'S A 2-YEAR-OLD KID.
I MEAN, YOU ASK HIM A QUESTION
AND YOU GET A 2-YEAR-OLD ANSWER.
"DO YOU LIKE YOU ROOM?"
A TRAIN?
"SO, WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF YOUR ROOM?"
TRAIN!
"AND YOUR ROOM -- YOU LIKE IT?"
OH!
TRAIN!
HE WASN'T EVEN
LISTENING TO ME
BECAUSE HE WAS TOO BUSY
GETTING INTO THINGS.
YOU GOT CEMENT TRUCKS
ON THE FLOOR.
YOU GOT COWBOY HATS.
WANT ONE ON?
YEEHAW, PARTNER!
I THINK THE PROOF
IS IN THE PUDDING.
HE LIKED THE ROOM.
WE'RE LIKE COWBOY BUDDIES,
ME AND YOU, AIN'T WE?
TRAIN.
[ LAUGHS ]
I FINALLY HAVE A PLACE TO WORK.
I'VE GOT A NEW OFFICE,
AND IT IS AN AWESOME OFFICE.
GOD, THIS IS SO AMAZING.
I MEAN, THIS THING IS AMAZING.
I'VE FINALLY GOT
A DEDICATED WORK SPACE.
OH, MY GOD.
I'VE GOT THE PROJECTION SCREEN,
TOUCHSCREEN --
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
HOW TO DESCRIBE IT
BECAUSE THAT THING
IS SO HIGH-TECH.
I LOVE IT, THOUGH.
I CAN TELL YOU THAT.
OH, WOW.
OH, MAN.
OH, THERE'S
SOME MISTLETOE.
WOW.
Kat: WALKING INTO THAT BEDROOM
FOR THE FIRST TIME WAS --
IT WAS A SENSE OF A PLACE
THAT WE HAD THAT WAS OURS.
THE PICTURE FRAME.
Shilo:
[ SIGHS ] GOODNESS.
OH, LOOK AT THE CHANDELIERS.
THIS IS AWESOME.
THIS IS SO BEAUTIFUL.
Kat: IT'S GONNA BE
JUST A WONDERFUL PLACE
TO ENJOY EACH OTHER
AND RECONNECT ON A LEVEL OF A
HUSBAND AND A WIFE AND A COUPLE
AND BE ABLE TO JUST ENJOY
THE PEACE THAT'S THERE.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
SO, COME ON IN.
OKAY, SO...
SO, YOUR BATHROOM
HAS ALSO GOT
ITS OWN AIR-FILTRATION
SYSTEM, OKAY?
SO, YOU'VE GOT SUPER-CLEAN,
FILTERED AIR.
THIS BATHTUB IS ACTUALLY
VERY, VERY DEEP,
JUST LIKE AT THE DOCTOR'S,
SO YOU CAN SUBMERGE
YOUR WHOLE BODY AND YOUR SKIN.
SO, THAT'S GOING TO BE VERY GOOD
FOR YOU FOR THERAPY,
BY SUBMERGING IN WATER.
YOU CAN CONTROL THE TEMPERATURE
OVER THERE,
AND YOU CAN ALSO SET
YOUR OWN MUSIC TO IT
SO IT ACTUALLY VIBRATES
AND SOOTHES YOU.
WOW.
DO WHATEVER YOU WANT.
AND OVER HERE,
THIS IS A VERY UNIQUE SHOWER.
THIS...
THIS IS WHAT YOU CALL --
IT'S -- IT'S A STEAM SHOWER.
AND SO WITH THAT RIGHT THERE,
YOU CAN ACTUALLY SET
THE TEMPERATURE
SO THE WATER
DOESN'T HAVE TO HIT YOUR SKIN,
BUT THE STEAM ITSELF
CAN ACTUALLY DO IT.
SO, THAT WAY,
IF THE WATER HURTS,
YOU CAN ACTUALLY JUST USE
THE STEAM.
THESE ARE ALL JUST WAYS
THAT MAKE LIFE A LITTLE EASIER,
A LITTLE LESS PAINFUL,
AND HOPEFULLY
A LITTLE MORE RELAXING.
Shilo:
THESE SURGERIES AND PROCEDURES
ARE GONNA CHALLENGE MY SKIN.
THERE'S STILL GONNA BE PAIN
ASSOCIATED WITH IT.
THERE'S STILL GONNA BE --
THE STEAM SHOWER, I THINK,
IS REALLY GONNA HELP WITH THAT.
LET'S GATHER THE FAMILY,
GET EVERYBODY TOGETHER
IN THE LIVING ROOM,
'CAUSE I'D LIKE TO SHOW YOU
SOMETHING OUTSIDE
YOU'RE REALLY GONNA WANT TO SEE.
ALL RIGHT?
OKAY. SOUNDS GOOD.
OH, WAIT.
OH, YEAH.
[ LAUGHS ]
I LIKE THE MISTLETOE.
THAT'S AWESOME.
THAT'S WHAT I WAS HOPING
WOULD HAPPEN.
[ BOTH LAUGH ]
.
SO, I KNOW BEFORE, LIKE, UM,
THERE WAS A REAL PROBLEM YOU HAD
WITH THE DUST
AND THE HEAT HERE, RIGHT?
AND YOU COULDN'T REALLY
SPEND ANY TIME OUTSIDE.
WELL, THIS WEEK, WE'VE
BEEN WORKING REALLY HARD
TO TRY AND FIX THAT.
WHAT WE'VE GOT GOING
IS SORT OF THE CHRISTMAS GIFT
YOU'VE ALWAYS SORT OF NEEDED,
WHICH WOULD BE
ABLE TO SPEND TIME WITH YOUR
FAMILY AND YOUR KIDS OUTSIDE.
SO, GUYS, GO CHECK OUT YOUR
BRAND-NEW OUTSIDE COURTYARD!
Shilo: ALL RIGHT!
OH, WOW!
HOLY COW!
ALL RIGHT!
WOW.
I THINK YOU GUYS ARE GONNA ENJOY
THIS SPACE QUITE A BIT.
OH, MY GOD.
PRETTY COOL, RIGHT?
Kat:
THIS IS GREAT. WOW.
SO, OUR FRIENDS AT SEARS
WANTED TO MAKE SURE
YOU GUYS HAD A COVERED SPACE
THAT'S PROTECTED FROM THE SUN
BUT YOU GUYS COULD ENJOY THE
GREAT OUTDOORS WITH YOUR FAMILY.
MICHAEL, WHY DON'T YOU EXPLAIN
ALL THE COOL STUFF OUT HERE?
YEAH, ABSOLUTELY.
I MEAN, FIRST OF ALL, WE KNOW
THAT YOU WANT TO JUST
BE WITH YOUR FAMILY,
AND I KNOW THE TEMPERATURES
HERE CAN BE PRETTY EXTREME,
SO WE DID OUR BEST TO MAKE IT AS
CLIMATE-CONTROLLED AS POSSIBLE.
SO, YOU SEE YOU'VE GOT FANS
UP HERE, AND THOSE ACTUALLY
ROTATE AND SPIN AROUND.
DO YOU SEE THE RINGS UP THERE?
THAT'S A COOLING SYSTEM.
YOU JUST FLIP A SWITCH
OVER HERE,
AND THAT'LL HELP REGULATE
THE TEMPERATURE OUT HERE
SO YOU CAN ENJOY
BEING OUTSIDE.
WOW.
HOW COOL IS THAT?
YOU FEEL THAT?
OH, YEAH.
BUT, OF COURSE,
YOU GOT THE BARBECUE
'CAUSE YOU GOT TO HAVE
A BARBECUE IN TEXAS, RIGHT?
Kat: OH, YEAH.
YOU GOT YOUR OUTDOOR
TELEVISION OUT HERE,
AND THEN, OF COURSE,
AIR HOCKEY.
THIS IS GONNA BE GREAT.
THIS IS GONNA BE
AN AMAZING TIME.
I'M GONNA BE RIGHT HERE,
CLOSE TO THE KIDS.
I LOVE IT.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
I THINK YOU GUYS ARE GONNA
SPEND A LOT OF TIME OUT HERE.
I THINK SO.
YEAH.
I KNOW I WOULD.
SO, WHAT DO YOU THINK?
YOU WANT TO OPEN SOME PRESENTS?
YEAH!
YES! YES! YES! YES!
WELL, ALL RIGHT! LET'S DO IT!
LET'S OPEN SOME PRESENTS!
Shilo: ALL RIGHT!
Kat:
THIS IS GONNA BE AN OPPORTUNITY
FOR MY FAMILY TO HAVE FUN
WHENEVER WE WANT TO.
SHILO'S GONNA BE ABLE
TO HAVE FUN
AND NOT SACRIFICE HIMSELF
SO MUCH
TO HAVE FUN WITH US
AND TO BE THE FATHER
IN THE BACKYARD, PLAYING.
HE CAN BE OUT THERE PLAYING
AND STEP UP ON THE PATIO
AND COOL OFF.
IT'S AMAZING.
GO CHECK OUT
YOUR BRAND-NEW BACKYARD!
ALL RIGHT!
THIS AIN'T A BACKYARD!
THIS IS A WINTER WONDERLAND!
[ LAUGHTER ]
SUMMER WONDERLAND,
SPRING WONDERLAND.
LOOK AT THAT, BUDDY.
WHOO!
ALL RIGHT.
I WAS THINKING ABOUT
FILMING A WESTERN, TOO.
[ LAUGHTER ]
THE WESTERN TOWN
AND THE HORSE --
THAT WAS MY FAVORITE.
BRANDY, COME HERE!
YAY! YOU SEE HER?
COME HERE.
THE BIG, RED BARN
WAS AMAZING.
THE HORSE IS GONNA BE
A NEW START,
AND IT'S GONNA GIVE ME A CHANCE
TO JUST LET THINGS GO AGAIN.
GOOD BABY GIRL.
AWW.
SHE KNOWS SHE'S HOME.
IT WAS A HOTEL, A JAIL CELL.
IT WAS SO COOL.
A LOCK --
I'LL LOCK YOU IN OVERNIGHT.
[ SCREAMS ]
[ LAUGHS ]
I'M GONNA BE
THE COOLEST COWGIRL IN TOWN.
FIRST OF ALL, WE GOT NEW CLUBS
FOR EVERYBODY, OKAY?
TOP OF THE LINE,
BRAND-NEW.
THIS -- THIS IS YOUR SET.
THESE AREN'T EVEN AVAILABLE YET.
SO, THIS RIGHT HERE
IS FOR YOU.
I KNOW YOUR PROBLEM WAS BEING
ABLE TO HOLD ON TO THE CLUB.
YEAH.
WE DID A LOT OF RESEARCH --
CAME UP WITH
WHAT WE COULD FIND FOR YOU
TO MAKE IT EASY FOR YOU
TO HOLD ON TO THE CLUB.
WE GOT SOME GUYS
WHO'LL COME IN.
THIS WILL BE
ACTUALLY CUSTOM-FITTED
TO WRAP AROUND
EVERY LITTLE NOOK AND CRANNY
SO IT'S REALLY
A TIGHT FIT.
I USED TO PLAY GOLF
WHEN I WAS ACTIVE DUTY
AND, OBVIOUSLY,
BEFORE I WAS INJURED.
I'M NOT SAYING
I WAS ANY GOOD AT IT,
BUT [LAUGHS]
IT WAS SOMETHING THAT I LOVED.
AFTER I WAS INJURED, YOU KNOW,
I HAD A LOT OF LIMITATIONS
WITH MY HANDS,
AND NOW I KNOW
THAT THERE'S A TECHNOLOGY THERE
THAT'S GONNA ALLOW ME
TO GET BACK OUT ON THE RANGE
AND LET ME HAVE
THAT OPPORTUNITY AGAIN.
THIS HAS BEEN AN HONOR
GETTING TO REALIZE
WHAT YOU GUYS DO,
WHAT YOU GO THROUGH,
AND HOW YOU COME OUT OF IT
WITH SUCH SPIRIT.
THAT'S YOUR OLD FLAGPOLE.
THERE'S MY FLAGPOLE.
THAT FLAGPOLE --
IT REPRESENTS SO MUCH.
IT REPRESENTS THE WARRIORS,
THE VETERANS, THE VOLUNTEERS
BEING OUT THERE.
THAT TELLS ME THAT AMERICA
IS DOING A PRETTY GOOD JOB
OF BACKING ITS FLAG
AND BACKING ITS SERVICEMEMBERS,
AND THAT MEANS A LOT.
I KNOW Y'ALL CARE.
THANK YOU.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Ty: ONE OF THE REASONS
THESE GUYS ARE HERE
IS I KNOW
THAT YOUR MISSION HAS BEEN
TO REALLY DO WHATEVER YOU CAN
TO HELP OUT WOUNDED WARRIORS.
SO, THIS WEEK,
WE'VE DONE EVERYTHING WE CAN
TO TRY AND HELP, AND WE
TEAMED UP WITH HELPING A HERO.
WE REALLY ARE HONORED
TO BE ABLE TO DO THIS.
YOU'VE TOUCHED A LOT OF PEOPLE.
SHILO, YOU'RE ALWAYS THERE
FOR ALL OF US OTHER SOLDIERS.
I ALWAYS SEE YOU
MOTIVATING ALL OF US,
AND SO TONIGHT,
ME AND ANTHONY --
WE'RE STARTING A LIFE
TOGETHER.
AS YOU CAN SEE,
I'M STILL SMILING.
[ LAUGHTER ]
I WOULD JUST LIKE TO SAY,
SHILO, MRS. HARRIS,
I'D JUST LIKE TO THANK
YOU GUYS SO MUCH
FOR EVERYTHING THAT YOU'VE DONE
FOR MY FAMILY.
STAFF SERGEANT DAN GILYEAT.
ABOUT FOUR YEARS AGO,
WE GOT AN EXTREME HOME MAKEOVER,
AND I COULDN'T HAVE BEEN
HAPPIER
WHEN I HEARD THAT YOU
WERE GONNA GET A HOUSE.
IT COULDN'T HAVE HAPPENED
TO A NICER PERSON.
THIS IS GONNA CHANGE YOUR LIFE
IN WAYS YOU HAVE NO IDEA,
BUT THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR WHAT
YOU DO AND CONTINUE TO SERVE.
[ APPLAUSE ]
Kat:
WE LOVE YOU GUYS, AND THANK YOU
FOR EVERYTHING THAT Y'ALL
HAVE DONE THIS WEEK.
GIVING FORWARD
IS THE BEST PAYBACK
FOR EVERYTHING WE'VE GOTTEN
UP TO THIS POINT,
SO WE'RE GONNA CONTINUE
TO DO THAT.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Shilo:
IT'S HUMBLING TO ME TO KNOW
THAT I WAS THE PERSON
ON THE RECEIVING END
OF SO MUCH GENEROSITY
AND SO MUCH LOVE,
AND I CAN'T THANK Y'ALL ENOUGH.
I CAN'T THANK
THE VOLUNTEERS ENOUGH.
I CANNOT THANK OUR NATION ENOUGH
FOR STANDING BEHIND US.
THANK ALL OF Y'ALL.
THANK ALL OF Y'ALL SO MUCH.
IT HAS BEEN AN HONOR THIS WEEK
TO NOT ONLY BUILD A HOME,
BUT TO BUILD, LITERALLY,
PLURAL HOMES.
SO, WHEN WE SAY OUR FINAL LINE,
WHICH IS "WELCOME HOME,"
IT'S NOT JUST TO THIS FAMILY.
IT'S TO ALL OF THE SOLDIERS.
WE ARE PROUD
TO BE ABLE TO SAY IT.
SO, WELCOME HOME.
AND, HARRIS FAMILY,
WELCOME HOME.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
TO FIND MORE ABOUT THE PRODUCTS
USED ON TONIGHT'S SHOW,
GO TO abc.com.
MERRY CHRISTMAS AND THANK YOU
TO ALL OF YOU
WHO ARE STILL SERVING.
KNOW THAT WE'RE
THINKING ABOUT YOU OUT THERE
EVERY SINGLE NIGHT,
EVERY SINGLE DAY.
BECAUSE YOU'RE FIGHTING
FOR OUR FREEDOM,
WE'RE ABLE TO DO WHAT WE CAN
OVER HERE TO HELP OTHERS.
YOU GUYS TAKE CARE OF ALL OF US
UNCONDITIONALLY.
I TRULY WISH YOU GUYS
A GREAT CHRISTMAS.
GOD BLESS YOU.
I THANK YOU FOR MY FREEDOM.
I'LL SEE YOU
WHEN YOU GUYS GET HOME.
Want to start the day
with something heart healthy
and delicious?
You're a talking bee...
Honey Nut Cheerios
has whole grain oats
that can help
lower cholesterol.
and it tastes good?
Sure does!
Right...
♪
Wow.
Delicious, right?
Yeah.
It's the honey,
it makes it taste so...
♪
Well, would you
look at the time...
What's the rush?
Be happy. Be healthy.
IT'S A CLASSIC SOUTHERN
DISH THAT A LOT OF
PEOPLE MISUNDERSTAND.
BUT FOR THIS NORTH
CAROLINA NATIVE IT'S FOOD
FOR MIND, SPIRIT AND BODY.
I'M DRINKING ALL OF THAT.
SEE WHY LEARNING THE SECRET OF
THIS FAVORITE FAMILY RECIPE FROM
HIS MOTHER TOOK OVER 20 YEARS.
WELL THAT'S GOOD.
AND WHY TODAY THAT
RECIPE TASTE OH SO GOOD.
NEXT ON MY FAMILY
RECIPE ROCKS.
♪  ♪
RALEIGH, NOR