ISSUE OF MENTAL HEALTH.
>>> A COMMUNITY IN MOURNING,
SHAKEN BY THIS TRAGEDY BUT
TONIGHT THERE'S A TREMENDOUS
OUTPOURING OF SUPPORT.
LAURA ANTHONY IS LIVE TONIGHT IN
SANDY HOOK, CONNECTICUT, WHERE
SHE SPOKE WITH FRIENDS OF THE
VICTIMS.
REPORTER: HI, AMA.
HERE'S THE LATEST ON THE
INVESTIGATION.
THE POLICE HAD A PRESS
CONFERENCE THIS AFTERNOON.
THEY HAVE COLLECTED A LARGE
AMOUNT OF EVIDENCE FROM THE HOME
THE SHOOTER SHARED WITH MISS
MOTHER.
IF THEY FOUND EVIDENCE OF A
MOTIVE THEY'RE NOT SHARING THAT
INFORMATION JUST YET.
WHY TIDE -- WHAT THEY TOLD US IS
THE HUNDREDS OF REQUIRES FIRED
INSIDE THE SCHOOL, HE LEFT
BEHIND A LARGE CACHE OF
AMMUNITION.
>> HIGH CAPACITY MAGAZINES.
>> TODAY CONNECTICUT STATE
POLICE REVEALED THAT AS MUCH
DAMAGE AS HE DID INSIDE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY, HE WAS POISED
TO DO MUCH MORE.
WITH HUNDREDS OF ROUND OF
UNSPENT BULLETS FOUND INSIDE THE
SCHOOL IN 30-ROUND MAGAZINES.
>> HIGH CAPACITY MAGAZINES FOR
THE RIFLE.
AND MULTIPLE MAGAZINES FOR THE
RIFLE.
AND MULTIPLE MAGAZINES FOR BOTH
HANDGUNS.
REPORTER: MEANTIME, THOUSANDS
CAME TO THIS TINY NEW ENGLAND
VILLAGE TO MOURN THOSE THAT
LANZA DID KILL.
MOST OF THEM CHILDREN AND THE
TEACHERS AND ADMINISTRATORS WHO
GAVE THEIR LIVES TRYING TO
PROTECT THEM.
NEAR THE ENTRANCE TO THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, THE DOOR IS
SURROUNDED BY CANDLES AND 27
CHRISTMAS TREES.
SOME CAME TO MOURN FROM FARWAY,
LIKE INDIANA.
>> IT'S JUST SO QUIET SO
PEACEFUL.
VERY SORRY FOR THE FAMILIES OF
THE VICTIMSMENT AND EVERYONE
HERE IN THIS TOWN.
IT'S VERY SAD.
>> JUST HAD TO HAVE SOME
CLOSURE.
IT'S A HORRIBLE THING.
REPORTER: MANY OF THOSE WHO CAME
BROUGHT STUFFED ANIMALS OR WERE
GIVEN ONE TO REMEMBER THE LITTLE
ONES LOST.
>> I JUST FELT REALLY SAD FOR
THE FAMILIES.
>> MOST OF THEM HAVE BEEN CRYING
>> SHE HAD A DOWNTOWN HAIR SALON
FOR CHILDREN.
MANY OF THE CHILDREN KILLED CAME
TO HER SALON.
>> THEY WERE JUST ADORABLE,
HAPPY, FUNNY, KIDS.
YOUR KIDS.
THEY WERE YOUR HEART.
AND THEY DIDN'T DESERVE FOR ANY
OF THIS TO HAPPEN.
REPORTER: THAT SHOPKEEPER WENT
ON TO TELL US THAT ONE OF THE
YOUNG VICTIMS ACTUALLY HAD AN
APPOINTMENT FOR A HAIR CUT AT
HER SALON YESTERDAY.
IT DIDN'T OCCUR TO HER HE WAS
AMONG THE VICTIM UNTIL SHE SAW
HIS NAME LISTED.
IN SANDY HOOK, CONNECTICUT,
ABC-7 NEWS.
>> Ama: AS THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN
GATHERED FOR WORRYSHIP TODAY TO
BEGIN THE PROCESS OF GRIEVING, A
CHURCH RECEIVED A BOMB THREAT.
THE THREAT WAS DIRECTED AT
ST. ROSE OF LIMA CHURCH.
FOR THE SECOND TIME IN THREE
DAYS S.W.A.T. TEAM MEMBERS IN
CAMOUFLAGE WERE BACK ON THE
STREETS IN NEWTOWN.
A THOUSAND PARISHIONERS WERE
EVACUATED.
>> WENT OUT CALMLY, A SAFE
RESOLUTION.
>> Ama: NO ONE WAS INJURED IN
THE INCIDENT.
EIGHT OF THE CHILD VICTIMS
ATTENDED THIS CHURCH, AS DO THE
SHOOTER ADAM LANZA AND HIS
MOTHER.
>> IN ADDITION TO THE BOMB
THREAT THERE ARE INSTANCES OF
PEOPLE GOING ONLINE TO SPREAD
FALSE INFORMATION ABOUT THE
SHOOTING.
>> THIS INFORMATION WILL BE
POSTED ON SOCIAL MEDIA SITES.
MISINFORMATION COMING FROM
PEOPLE POSING AS THE SHOOTER IN
THIS CASE, POSING -- USING OTHER
I.D.ES, MIMICKING THIS CRIME
SCENE, THE ACTIVITY IN THIS
COMMUNITY.
>> Ama: CURRENTLY INVESTIGATING
WHO IS BEHIND THIS.
THEY ASSURED REPORTERS, ANYONE
ARRESTED WILL BE PROSECUTED TO
THE FULL EXTENT OF THE LAW.
>> A FRIEND OF THE FAMILY SAYS
ADAM LANZA LEARNED HOW TO SHOOT
GUNS FROM HIS MOM.
HE SAID THEY WERE HER HOBBY.
AUTHORITIES FOUND THREE GUNS
USED IN THE SHOOTING THAT BELONG
TO HIS MOTHER.
INCLUDING A GLOCK, A MINE
MILLIMETER HANDGUN AND AN SAUL
RIFLE.
POLICE SEARCHED THE LANZA HOME
AND TOOK COMPUTERS FOR THEIR
INVESTIGATION.
>> STAY WITH COOPS COOPS FOR --
ABC-7 NEWS FOR CONTINUING CONK
COVERAGE OF THE TRAGEDY, AND
SIGN UP FOR OUR BREAKING HUSBAND
NEWS NEWSLETTER.
>> IN THE BAY AREA, MANY ARE
TURNING TO THEIR CHURCHES FOR
SOLACE.
WE'RE LIVE AT ST. MARY'S
CATHEDRAL IN SAN FRANCISCO.
>> PARENTS HELD THEIR CHILDREN
VERY TIGHT TODAY AND HERE AT THE
CATHEDRAL, SPECIAL AREA HAS BEEN
SET ASIDE FOR PARISHIONERS TO
PRAY FOR THE NEWTOWN VICTIMS.
AT MORNING MASS HERE, THIS
SPECIAL PRAYER WAS WRITTEN FOR
THE VICTIMS OF NEWTOWN.
A PARISHIONER HAD PLAYERS
ALREADY PLANNED.
>> TODAY IS THE DAY TO PRAY,
ESPECIALLY FOR ALL OF THE PEOPLE
THAT WERE MASSACRED, AND FOR THE
FAMILIES.
>> THE MONSIGNOR IS THE PASTOR
OF ST. MARY'S AND SAYS PEOPLE
HAVE COME TO MASS NOT JUST TO
PRAY BUT TO TRY TO MAKE SENSE OF
THE EVIL THAT OCCURRED.
>> AND SEEKING TO FIND
CONSOLATION IN THE PROMISE AND
HOPE OF A GOD WHO FEELS WITH US
AND LONGS TO HELP US.
♪
>> AT GLIDE MEMORIAL CHURCH,
THEY DID WHAT IT DOES BEST,
HELPED ITS CONGREGATION
CELEBRATE LIFE WHILE RECOVERING
FROM THE SORROW OF THE TRAGEDY.
THE CHURCH WAS FILLED TO
STANDING ROOM ON AND SAYS THE
RESPONSE TO THIS EVENT IS
INCREDIBLE.
>> NEVER SEEN IT TOUCHED LIKE
THIS.
NEVER SEEN IT TOUCHED
COMMUNITIES AND INDIVIDUALS LIKE
THIS IS DOING.
>> HE SAYS THE KILLING OF
INNOCENTS HAS AFFECTED PEOPLE
EVERY.
>> IT HAPPENS ALL OVER THE
WORLD.
HE WENT TO DESTROY THE CHILDREN.
FOR SOME REASON.
REPORTER: MANY OF THE PEOPLE
CAME WITH THEIR CHILDREN HELD
TIGHT, THIS IS HER FIRST VISIT
TO GLIDE CHURCH.
SHE BROUGHT HER DAUGHTER ALONG.
>> FIRST TIME HERE, AND THIS --
JUST TO SHARE THE LOVE AND THE
HEARTACHE THAT EVERYBODY IS
FEELING.
TREMENDOUS HEARTACHE.
>> BECAUSE OF THAT HEART WAIK,
THE HILLSBORO BURLINGAME
COMMUNITY WILL BE HOLDING A
SPECIAL VILLAGELE AND PRAYER
SERVICE AT THE FIRST
PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH IN
BURLINGAME.
>> Ama: YOU CAN EXPRESS YOUR
SEPTEMBER THE BY POSTING THIS
BADGE TO YOUR FACEBOOK WALL.
>> STILL TO COME, NEW DETAILS
NOT DEADLY ACCIDENT INVOLVING A
BAY AREA CHP OFFICER.
>>> PLUS, GIVING BACK.
A GROUP THAT WANTS YOU TO ADD ON
TO THEIR RANDOM ACTS OF
KINDNESS.
>> WHAT THE HOBBIT DID THAT
"LORD OF THE RINGS" COULD NOT.
LYING LYING LIVE DOPPLER 7HD
PICKING UP SOME RAIN.
WE'LL ALONG AT THAT, PLUS A LOOK
AT THE AccuWeather
>> Ama: WE NOW KNOW THE NAME OF
THE CHP OFFICER KILLED FRIDAY
NIGHT.
OFFICER JOHN DINEEN DIED AFTER
HIS BIKE CLIPPED A TRUCK THAT
TURNED IN FRONT OF HIM.
THE ACCIDENT IS UNDER
INVESTIGATION.
DRUGS AND ALCOHOL ARE NOT
BELIEVED TO BE A FACTOR.
>>> DEVELOPING NEWS OUT OF
CORROSION CONTRACOST COSTA
COUNTY.
A DRIVER FLIPPED HER CAR AND IT
BURST INTO FLAMES.
NO ONE WAS INJURED.
>>> OFFICIALS ARE INVESTIGATING
AN OFFICER-INVOLVED SHOOTING IN
SUNNYVALE LAST NIGHT.
TWO OFFICERS WERE RESPONDING TO
A CALL THAT MAN WAS ASSAULTING
HIS MOTHER.
POLICE SAY THE MAN APPROACHED
OFFICERS WITH A HAMMER, WHEN HE
REFUSED TO DROP IT, OFFICERS
FIRED.
THE SUSPECT UNDERWENT SURGERY.
HIS CONDITION IS NOT KNOWN.
>> IF YOU HAVEN'T MAILED YOUR
CHRISTMAS GIFTS YOU MIGHT WANT
TO BE PREPARED FOR LONG LINES.
>> AND HANDING OUT RANDOM ACTS
OF KINDNESS.
A GROUP THAT HOPES TO MAKE A
DIFFERENCE FOR OTHERS THIS
HOLIDAY SEASON.
>> MORE RAIN HEADING OUR WAY,.
>> Leigh:  --
>> Leigh: IS UP NEXT WITH THE
FORECAST.
AND...
TAKE CARE OF THEM,
YOU KNOW?
I FEEL LIKE WE'VE
COME FULL CIRCLE.
LIKE THAT!
THIS IS HOW
I'LL DO IT.
Sarah:
THERE YOU GO.
>> Ama: THE POST OFFICE IS
GEARING UP FOR THE BUSIEST DAY
OF THE YEAR.
THE MONDAY BEFORE CHRISTMAS IS
TRADITIONALLY THE BUSIEST DAY,
THE LAST DAY TO GET FIRST CLASS
MAIL OUT IN TIME TO ARRIVE BY
CHRISTMAS.
USPS EXPECT 800 MILLION PIECES
OF MAIL TO BE HANDLED TOMORROW.
40% MORE THAN THE AVERAGE DAY.
>> IN THE HOLIDAY SEASON AND
TRYING TIMES A KIND GESTURE CAN
GO A LONG WAY.
THAT'S WHY SOME GOOD PEOPLE SET
UP AN AID BOOTH AT THE FARMERS
MARKET.
PEOPLE WERE MET WITH A KIND
WORD, ENCOURAGING NOTES, AND
FREE HUGS FROM VOLUNTEERS FROM
THE HUNTING HAPPINESS PROJECT.
>> I WAS JUST WALKING BY, GOING
TO LOOK AT SOME TOMATOES AND
STUFF SUSPICIOUS SOMEBODY GAVE
ME THIS NOTE, AND ASKED ME IF I
WANTED A HUG, AND I GOT TWO HUGS
FROM STRANGERS, COMPLETE
STRANGERS, AND I THOUGHT IT WAS
HART-WARMING CONSIDERING WHAT IS
GOING ON IN THE WORLD.
>> Ama: ALONG WITH RANDOM ACTS
OF KINDNESS, THE PROJECT HELPS
PEOPLE WITH HUNGER, HOUSING, AND
EMPLOYMENT NEEDS.
>> THE AT&T IS DECKED OUT IN
ORANGE AND BLACK, FITTING AS
FANS ENJOY A SPECIAL GIANTS
MEMORABILIA SALE TODAY.
PROCEEDS FROM THE SALE AND
AUCTION WILL GOOD TO SUPPORT THE
GIANT'S COMMUNITY FUND.
>> GET READY FOR MORE SNOW IN
THE SIERRA.
HERE'S VIDEO FROM THE TAHOE CAM.
LOTS OF SNOW ALREADY, AND MORE
IS EXPECTED.
SNOW WILL FALL TONIGHT AND SNOW
LEVELS WILL CONTINUE TO DROP
OVER THE NEXT FEW DAYS.
AND CHECK OUT THIS SNOW.
A VIEWER SENT THIS PHOTO OF SNOW
NEAR -- MT. -- WHICH IS
2500 FEET.
>> Leigh: LAST NIGHT WE TALKED
ABOUT SOUTH LAKE COUNTY COULD
SEE SNOW.
WE WERE RIGHT ON THAT.
IF YOU HAVE BEEN IN THE NORTH
BAY, MARIN COUNTY, ALL DAY LONG,
EVEN SONOMA COUNTY, NAPA COUNTY,
THE LOW-LEVEL MOISTURE MOVING IN
AND WET PAVEMENT ON THE GOLDEN
GATE BRIDGE AND ALSO A LOT OF
FOG DEVELOPING.
SO TRICKY TRAVEL THIS EVENING.
WE'LL DO THE SAME THING TOMORROW
MORNING AS WELL BUT YOU HAVE TO
DEAL WITH MODERATE RAIN.
LIVE DOPPLER 7HD PICKING UP A
LITTLE BIT OF THIS LOW-LEVEL
MOISTURE.
NOT PICKING UP A LOT OF IT OUT
THERE.
YOU CAN SEE IT'S MAINLY CENTERED
IN THE NORTH BAY.
SANTA ROSA, PETALUMA, SONOMA,
SOME RETURNS PICKING UP THERE.
HEADING OVER TOWARDS NAPA, AND
OVER TOWARDS AMERICAN CANYON,
BUT ELSEWHERE, IF IT'S COMING
DOWN, IT'S SO LIGHT THE RADAR
BEAM IS SWEEPING LIVE BUT CAN'T
PICK IT UP, WHICH I TYPICALLY
THE CASE AND YOU CAN SEE A
LITTLE RETURNS HERE AND THERE
EAST OF SAN JOSE.
RIGHT NOW, 49 IN SANTA ROSA.
50s ELSEWHERE ACROSS THE BAY
AREA, AND HERE'S A LOOK AT THE
FORECAST.
RAIN WILL INCREASE OVERNIGHT.
WE HAVE ANOTHER COLD FRONT DUE
IN HERE OVERNIGHT.
GET READY FOR A WET MORNING
COMMUTE.
AND THEN STORMY OUTLOOK.
LOOKS LIKE, TOWARDS THE LATTER
PART OF OUR WORK WEEK.
THIS HAS BEEN A STORM SYSTEM,
THIS WARMER SECTOR IS
RESPONSIBLE FOR THE HEAVY MIST
AND DRIZZLE NORTH OF THE GOLDEN
GATE BRIDGE TODAY.
THE CLOUDS WILL THICKEN ACROSS
THE BAY AREA AS THE STORM MOVES
IN AND RAIN ON THE INCREASE,
HERE'S OUR TIMING.
THE FORECAST BEGINNING AT
8:00 TONIGHT, YOU CAN SEE MOD --
MODERATE RAIN MOVING MOVING IN N
BY MIDNIGHT WE ARE LOOKING AT
THE BAND OF REASON FROM THE
NORTH BAY TO IN THE SOUTH BAY.
THIS IS OUR 5:00 A.M. COMMUTE
TOMORROW.
ALLOW EXTRA DRIVE TIME IT'S
GOING TO BE WET AND BREEZY BY
8:00 A.M. SHOULD SEE A LITTLE
CLEARING IN THE NORTH BAY.
SHOWERS WILL CONTINUE TO MOVE
SOUTH BY 5:00 COMMUTE TOMORROW
EVENING, WE SHOULD SEE PARTIAL
CLEARING, AND AFTER THAT, GET
READY FOR CLEAR SKY FOR MUCH OF
THE BAY AREA IN THE SIERRA, A
WINTER WEATHER ADVISORY UNTIL
10:00 TOMORROW.
MAYBE A FOOT OF SNOW AT LAKE
LEVEL, CLOSE TO TWO FEET NEAR
THE 7,000-FOOT LEVEL.
SO KEEP THAT IN MIND CHAIN
REQUIREMENTS WILL MORE THAN
LIKELY BE ISSUED OVERNIGHT
TONIGHT AND TOMORROW.
LOWS TONIGHT WITH INCREASING
RAIN.
50s TO UPPER 40s.
MUCH WARMER THAN LAST NIGHT.
AND HERE'S A LOOK AT THE HIGHS
FOR TOMORROW.
REMEMBER, MORNING COMMUTE,
THAT'S WENT THE RAIN, AND IT
COULD BE HEAVY AT TIME --S MOVES
IN.
AND NOT A LOT OF WARMING
TOMORROW, TEMPERATURES
MID-TO-LOW 50s.
HERE'S THE SEVEN-DAY FORECAST.
WE GET A BREAK ON TUESDAY AND
WEDNESDAY, AND THEN A STRONGER
STORM MOVES IN WITH HEAVY RAIN
AND WIND THURSDAY NIGHT, FRIDAY
MORNING, PERIODS OF RAIN ON
FRIDAY, AND THEN THE FORECAST
MODEL SUGGESTING ANOTHER STRONG
STORM MOVING IN ON SATURDAY
THROUGH EARLY SUNDAY MORNING.
WE WILL KEEP YOU UPDATED ON
THAT.
AND MIKE NICO WILL BE HERE
TOMORROW MORNING, 4:30, TO 7:00,
TO GET YOU OUT THE DOOR.
>> Ama: SHU IS HERE WITH SPOTS.
RAIDERS PLAYING AT HOME.
>> Mike: COASTING KANSAS CITY IN
THEIR FINAL HOME GAME OF THE
SEASON.
LAST TEAM THEY BEAT?
KANSAS CITY.
THIS RAIDER FAN OFFERING HER
PAIRS TO THE VICTIMS OF NEWTOWN.
BRADY QUINN PICKED OFF, LEADING
TO A GRANDCOW SKI FIELD GOAL.
6-0 RAIDERS.
THIS 19 YARDER LED TO THE FOURTH
FIELD GO MIKE GOODSON, STRONG
GAME ON THE GROUND.
SPINS AWAY FROM ONE TACKLE.
43 OF HIS 89 YARDS ON THEGROUND,
AND THIS, LED TO A FIELD GOAL.
BUT THE RAIDERS DEFENSE DID SHUT
OUT THE CHIEFS.
FIRST SINCE 2002.
TOMMY KELLY, FIRST SACK OF THE
SEASON.
RAIDERS SNAP A SIX-GAME SKID,
15-THE FINAL.
>> OUR GUYS NEEDED SOMETHING
WHERE THEY GET A LITTLE
CONFIDENCE, AND I THOUGHT THEY
HAD A GREAT WEEK OF PRACTICE.
I THOUGHT THEY WERE TOTALLY
FOCUSED ON WHAT WE NEEDED TO DO
AND HOW WE NEEDED TO PLAY TO WIN
THIS FOOTBALL GAME, AND I
THOUGHT THEY DID A GREAT JOB
EXECUTING TODAY.
>> Mike: AROUND THE AFC.
ANDREW LUCK FIGHTING FOR A WILD
CARD SPOT IN HOUSTON.
THE PUNT BLOCKED.
THE SCOOP AND SCORE.
23-TEXANS.
ANDREW LUKE THROUGH FOR
186 YARDS, TWO T.D.ES, INCLUDING
THIS ONE TO HIT TON.
THAT WAS NOT ENOUGH.
TEXAN IMPROVE TO 12-2 WITH THE
VICTORY.
>> DEN VERS SEALED THE AFC WEST
EFFECTS AGO BUT HAVE A CHANCE
FOR TO TOP SPOT IN THE AFC.
MADE A STATEMENT IN BALTIMORE.
PICKING OFF JOE FLACCO, GOES
90 YARDS.
PEYTON MANNING THREW ONLY ONE
T.D. PASS, THIS STRIKE TO ERIC
DECKER.
HE HAD 133-YARD RECEIVING.
BRONCOS WITH THE NINE, GAME WIN
STREAK, 34-17 THE FINAL.
RAVENS STILL LEAD THEIR
DIVISION.
>> IF THE PATRIOTS BEAT SAN
FRANCISCO TONIGHT THEY'LL HAVE
THE HOME FIELD ADVANTAGE.
LE SEAHAWKS KEEPING THE PRESSURE
ON THE 49ers.
THEY BEAT THE BILLS, QUARTERBACK
RUSSELL WILSON RAP FOR THREE
T.D.ES IN THE GAME AND THE
DEFENSE GAME UP BIG FOR THE
SEAHAWKS.
THOMAS, PICKED OFF RYAN
FITZPATRICK, TAKES IT 57 YARDS
THE OTHER WAY.
NINERS FACE THE RED-HOT SEAHAWKS
NEXT SUNDAY IN SEATTLE.
SEAHAWKS WIN 50-17.
>>> FALL TONS, THE TEAM TO BET
IN THE NFC SHOWING I WOULD
TODAY.
MAT RHINE HITS TONY GONZALEZ.
14-0 ATLANTA.
FOURTH QUARTER, RYAN COULDN'T DO
ANYTHING WRONG.
270 YARDS, FALCONS WITH THE 34-0
SHUTOUT OVER THE GIANTS.
>>> PACKERS AND BEARS.
WHAT A GAME FOR SAN JOSE STATE
ALUM JAMES JONES.
THREE T.D. CATCHES.
GREEN BAY CLINCHES THE NFC NORTH
FOR THE SECOND STRAIGHT SEASON
AND IF THE 49ers LOSE THE
PACKERS WITH PASS THEM FOR THE
SECOND SEED IN THE NFC.
41-13 THE FINAL.
>> COWBOYS STILL IN THE PLAYOFF,
FACING THE STEELERS.
OVERTIME, BEN ROETHLISBERGER
PICKED OFF BY CARR WHO TAKES IT
IN TO THE ONE YARDLINE.
DALLAS WITH THE FIELD GOAL TO
WIN.
COWBOYS IN A THREE-WAY TIE WITH
WASHINGTON AND THE GIANTS FOR
THE NFC DIVISION.
>> AND ADRIAN PETERSON LED THE
VIKINGS OVER THE ST. LOUIS RAMS,
212 YARDS RUSHING AND ONE CHINA.
294 YARDS SHY OF THE ALL-TIME
RECORD.
HE COULD GIVE IT WITH TWO GAMES
LEFT.
>> Ama: IT WOULD BE GREAT IF
BOTH OUR TEAMS WIN TODAY.
A RETURN TO MIDDLE EARTH JUST
AHEAD.
HOW "THE HOBBIT" STACKS UP TO
>> Ama: JOIN ME AT 9:00 ON CABLE
13.
WE'LL TAKE A LOOK AT A MASSIVE
ASTEROID THREE MILES WIDE.
AT IT CONSIDERED A POTENTIAL
THREAT BUT NOT FOR SEVERAL
CENTURIES.
AND IT'S BACK TO SCHOOL TOMORROW
AND AFTER FRIDAY'S SHOOTING IT
CAN BE SCARY EVEN FOR KIDS IN
THE BAY AREA.
TONIGHT THE ONE THING YOU SHOULD
TELL YOUR KID BEFORE THEY HEAD
TO SCHOOL.
>>> MIDDLE EARTH IS BACK ON TOP
AT THE BOX OFFICE.
>> Ama: PETER JACKSON'S "THE
HOBBIT" TOOK IN NEARLY
$85 MILLION IN THE
RECORD-SETTING OPENING, STRONGER
THAN THE THREE PREVIOUS "LORD OF
THE RINGS" FILMS, AND GUARDIANS
PULLED IN THE FAMILY CROWD.
LINCOLN CROSSED THE
$100 MILLION MARK.
SKYFALL IS STILL HANGING ON.
COMING IN AT NUMBER FOUR.
AND "LIFE OF PI" WRAPS UP THE
TOP FIVE FILMS.
THAT DOES IT FOR US AT 6:00.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR JOINING US
THIS EVENING.
WE HAVE FREE APPS FOR YOUR
SMARTPHONE AND DOWNLOAD OUR
LARGE CLOCK APP FOR FREE FROM
APPLE'S APP STORE AND AMAZON APP
STORE.
SEE YOU LATER TONIGHT.
LEAVING YOU WITH A LIVE LOOK AT
THE BAY BRIDGE.
♪
♪ RIGHT NOW, THE GOLDEN
GLOBE NOMINATIONS!
>> ELLEN MIR IN.
>> ZERO DARK THIRTY.
>> HOMELAND.
>> HUGH JACKMAN, THE
HOLLYWOOD STAR.
>> THIS IS COME HATLY
SURREAL.
>> BARBRA STREISAND TALKS
ROAD TRIPS!
>> IT WAS REALLY FUN.
>> 'S GLAD I IT DID.
>> AND HAVING FUN WITH A TV
PRESIDENT.
>> IT IS KIND OF LIKE
PULLING BACK THE COVERS, YOU
KNOW.
>> WE'RE ROLLING THE RED
CARPET NOW.
>> HI, I'M BILL PULMAN AND
YOU ARE WATCHING ON THE RED
CARPET.
♪
>> WELCOME TO ON THE RED
CARPET FROM THE SET