OF THE SUNOL GRADE HEADING DOWN
80.
680 AND 880 INTO MILPITAS.
ALL THE WAY TO LAWRENCE
EXPRESSWAY AND MOFFETT FIELD
GETTING WET WEATHER.
BEST RETURNS UP IN THE SANTA
CRUZ MOUNTAINS.
THIS IS ALL MOVING WEST TO EAST.
IT'S GOING TO BE HERE THROUGH
9:00.
IT'S ALSO A LITTLE GUSTY OUT
THERE.
WINDS FROM 6-17 MILES AN HOUR,
EVEN UP TO 30 AT THE COAST.
ONCE WE GET PAST NOON, AFTERNOON
SHOWERS POSSIBLE.
>>> WE HAVE LIGHT TRAFFIC COMING
OUT OF MARIN COUNTY THROUGH THE
WALDO TUNNEL ON THE GOLDEN GATE
BRIDGE.
YOU CAN SEE IT IS WET.
IT IS WINDY OUT THERE.
BRIDGES USE EXTRA CAUTION.
YOU WILL HAVE FOUR LANES
SOUTHBOUND.
YOU CAN SEE HAZE OVER THE CAMERA
AS YOU LOOK TOWARDS THE GOLDEN
GATE FIELDS AREA, BERKELEY AND
INTO THE MacARTHUR MAZE.
IT MAY BE CLOUDY AND LIMITED
VISIBILITY.
HERE IS COMMUTE TIMES.
880 IN SOUTHBOUND DIRECTION
TOWARD 238 AND THEN 238 TOWARD
84 AND EASTBOUND OUT OF SAN
RAFAEL, 580 OVER TO THE
RICHMOND-SAN RAFAEL BRIDGE ABOUT
18 MINUTES.
>> Kristen: RAINING MONDAY
MORNING COULD BE A CHALLENGING
COMMUTE ESPECIALLY DANGEROUS IN
THE MOUNTAINS.
TERRY McSWEENEY IS LIVE IN THE
SANTA CRUZ MOUNTAINS AND TERRY,
LIVE DOPPLER 7-HD SAYS YOU
SHOULD BE GETTING WET AND LOOKS
LIKE YOU ARE.
>> THAT LIVE DOPPLER 7-HD, IT IS
CORRECT.
IT'S NOT COMING DOWN THAT HARD
BUT COMING DOWN SINCE AT LEAST
3:30 THIS MORNING.
IT WAS COMING DOWN WHEN HE HIT
IT AND COMING BACK FROM MOST OF
THE RIDE THIS SIDE OF LOS GATOS.
WE HAVE RAIN TO TALK ABOUT UP
HERE.
WE HAVE RAIN TO TALK ABOUT NORTH
OF HERE.
TAKE A LOOK AT SOME PICTURES
THIS MORNING FROM THE GOLDEN
GATE BRIDGE WHERE THE RAIN WAS
COMING DOWN, A LITTLE HARDER
THAN IT IS HERE.
AS I WENT FROM SOUTHERN MARIN
DOWN TO SAN JOSE, POCKETS OF
LIGHT RAIN, THEN IT WAS DRY,
THEN THERE WERE STARS ABOVE AND
THEN MORE RAIN.
IT'S ALL OVER THE MAP.
I WAS COMING DOWN THIS WAY THIS
MORNING.
COMMUTE IS NOT AFFECTED, THE
RAIN IS REALLY VERY LIGHT.
IT'S BEING LIT UP BY THE LIGHTS
WE HAVE ON DOWN HERE.
THERE IS THE MIST AND SOME RAIN
IN PLACES AND SOME STRONG WINDS
UP IN THE NORTH BAY, AS WELL.
AS OF RIGHT NOW, NOT IMPACTING
THE COMMUTE BUT IT IS COMING
DOWN AND HAS BEEN FOR AT LEAST A
FEW HOURS.
>> Eric: WE'RE JUST MINUTES AWAY
FROM A LIVE UPDATE ON THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT.
HERE ARE THE TOP DEVELOPMENTS AT
5:00.
A SCHOOL NURSE WHO SURVIVED THE
ATTACK BY TAKING COVER BENEATH
HER DESK IS TELLING HER STORY TO
ABC NEWS.
SALLY SAYS SHE HEARD THE INITIAL
GUNSHOTS OUTSIDE AND THE SCHOOL
SECRETARY CALLED OUT TO HER.
SHE DOVE UNDER HER DESK.
YOU WILL HEAR THE REST OF HER
STORY COMING UP ON "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA."
IN NEWTOWN THEY ARE SENDING
THEIR CHILDREN TO OTHER SCHOOLS
AS SANDY HOOK REMAINS CLOSED.
>> BAY AREA SCHOOLS ARE
ADDRESSING CONCERNS ABOUT SCHOOL
SECURITY AS KIDS HEAD BACK TO
THE CLASSROOMS THIS MORNING.
SOME SCHOOL DISTRICTS HAVE
REACHED OUT TO POLICE
DEPARTMENTS TO REVIEW SAFETY
PROCEDURES.
FOR OTHER DISTRICTS LIKE IN
OAKLAND, THE THREAT OF VIOLENCE
IS SOMETHING THEY DEAL WITH ON A
REGULAR BASIS.
TEACHERS ARE BEING BRIEFED ON
HOW TO DISCUSS ANY QUESTIONS
STUDENTS MIGHT HAVE ABOUT
FRIDAY'S SHOOTING IN CONNECTICUT
AMY HOLLYFIELD WILL HAVE MUCH
MORE IN A LIVE REPORT COMING UP
IN 30 MINUTES.
>> OUT OF THE TRAGEDY AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY THERE IS A
REMARKABLE ON STORY OF SURVIVAL
THIS MORNING.
A LITTLE GIRL TEACHER TOLD HER
TO PLAY DEAD.
SHE WAS THE ONLY ONE TO MAKE IT
OUT LIVE.
>> SHE WAS THE FIRST TO RUN OUT
OF SCHOOL BUILDING COVERED IN
BLOOD FROM HEAD TO TOE.
IN THE FIRST WORD SAID, MOMMY,
I'M OKAY, BUT ALL MY FRIENDS ARE
DEAD.
>> THE PASTOR AND THE LITTLE
GIRL'S FAMILY IS SUFFERING
SURVIVAL'S GUILT.
>> THERE ARE HEAVY HEARTS AROUND
THE GLOBE.
AS FAMILY AND FRIENDS GATHERED
FOR A SERVICE IN NEWTOWN,
PRESIDENT OBAMA SPOKE TO THE
CROWD IN HOPES OF STARTING THE
HEALING PROCESS FOR A HURTING
NATION.
GOOD MORNING.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING.
TODAY WILL BE ANOTHER DIFFICULT
DAY FOR THIS GRIEVING COMMUNITY.
FIRST VICTIMS WILL BE LAID TO
REST DURING FUNERALS TODAY AND
AT LAST NIGHT'S VIGIL, IT WAS AN
EMOTIONAL SCENE SOMETHING THIS
COMMUNITY AND COUNTRY WILL NOT
SOON FORGET.
>> OLIVIA, JOSEPHINE.
>> MORE THAN 900 MOURNERS HEARD
AN EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT OBAMA
ADMIT THE COUNTRY HAS FAILED
THEM.
>> SINCE I'VE BEEN PRESIDENT
THIS IS THE FOURTH TIME WE'VE
COME TOGETHER TO COMFORT A
GRIEVING COMMUNITY TORN APART BY
MASS SHOOTINGS.
>> HE WILL USE THE POWER OF THE
PRESIDENCY TO STOP THE TRAGEDY
LIKE THE MASSACRE OF 26 CHILDREN
AND ADULTS AT SANDY HOOK.
>> THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END AND
TO END THEM WE MUST CHANGE.
>> AN EMOTIONAL REACTION FROM
THE SHATTERED COMMUNITY TO THE
PRESIDENT'S VISIT.
>> IT DID MEAN A LOT.
>> WE HAVE SIX KIDS.
LIKE YOU SAID, THAT IS HOW WE
WILL BE JUDGED.
>> NEW AND CHILLING DETAILS
ABOUT THE GUNMAN'S PAST HAVE
EMERGED.
RAMPAGE ENDED TEN MINUTES AFTER
IT BEGIN WHEN LANZA IN THE
SECOND CLASSROOM WHERE HE OPENED
FIRE HEARD WAILING SIRENS AND
SHOT HIMSELF ONCE IN THE HEAD.
>> IT WAS DURING THE SECOND
CLASSROOM EPISODE THAT HE HEARD
RESPONDERS COMING AND APPARENTLY
DECIDED TO TAKE HIS OWN LIFE.
>> ALSO THIS MORNING, NEW CLUES
ABOUT THE 20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER.
COMPUTERS AND VIDEOS WERE
REMOVED FROM THE LANZA FAMILY
HOME THAT COULD PROVIDE CLUES
INTO THE MOTIVE.
FRIENDS OF THE MURDERED MOTHER
SAID SHE BECAME CONCERNED LAST
MOST ABOUT HER SON'S BEHAVIORAL
ISSUES.
>> IT WAS DIFFICULT TO GET HIM
IN REGULAR LIFE.
>> ALL OF THE SCHOOLS IN THE
AREA ARE CLOSED TODAY AND
STUDENTS FROM SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WILL RESUME
CLASSES ON WEDNESDAY AT A NEARBY
SCHOOL.
>>> BEFORE YOU GET AWAY, WE KNOW
POLICE HAVE BEEN ZEROING ON ADAM
AND HIS MOM.
WHAT MORE HAVE WE LEARNED ABOUT
THEM?
>> Reporter: ABC NEWS HAS
LEARNED THAT ADAM AND HIS MOTHER
RECENTLY VISITED A LOCAL GUN
RANGE.
WHAT THEY ARE TRYING TO FIND OUT
WHETHER LANZA WOULD SHOOT THERE
AND IF HE ATTEMPTED TO PURCHASE
GUNS THERE.
THAT IS THE CENTER OF THE
INVESTIGATION.
THAT IS WHAT THEY ARE LOOKING
INTO AT THIS MOMENT.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
YOU CAN EXPRESS YOUR SYMPATHY
FOR THE VICTIMS SANDY HOOK
TRAGEDY BY POSTING THIS BADGE ON
YOUR FACEBOOK WALL.
YOU CAN FIND IT AT ABC7NEWS.COM
AND USE IT AS SHOW OF SUPPORT
FOR PEOPLE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WE'LL CONTINUE TO COVER THE
STORY AS IT UNFOLDS.
FIND THE LATEST DEVELOPMENTS AT
ABC7NEWS.COM AS WELL AS OUR
FACEBOOK PAGE AND TWITTER FEEDS.
>>> LATE LAST NIGHT IT STARTED
TO RAIN AND IT CONTINUED THIS
MORNING.
WE SAW THE VISIBILITY PRETTY LOW
THIS MORNING.
>> THAT IS WHAT IS WAITING FOR
YOU.
LIGHT RAIN, WATER ON THE
ROADWAYS, IT'S GOING TO BE SLICK
COMMUTE THIS MORNING AND YOU CAN
SEE LIVE DOPPLER SHOWING SOME
RADAR RETURNS WITH HEAVIER RAIN
UP AROUND NAPA HEADING OVER SO
LANO WE'RE GETTING SOME GREENS
PROBABLY JUST LIGHT RAIN, MORE
TO THE GROUND IN AN EARNEST
FASHION THAN ANYPLACE ELSE.
TWO AND A HALF MOVATO, FOG NOT A
BIG ISSUE IN MORNING BUT THE
LIGHT RAIN IS CAUSING THE
REDUCTION IN VISIBILITY.
IT'S VERY MILD WHEN YOU STEP OUT
THIS MORNING.
LOW TO MID 50s AND TEMPERATURES
AREN'T GOING TO CHANGE DURING
THE AFTERNOON HOURS.
BE PREPARED FOR THIS DURING THE
AFTERNOON HOURS.
LIGHT RAIN THROUGH 7:00, A FEW
SHOWERS THROUGH NOON AND SHOWERS
WILL BE LESS LIKELY BY 4:00 AND
CLEARING BY 7:00 AND
TEMPERATURES IN THE MID TO UPPER
40s.
SCATTERED FROST POSSIBLE THROUGH
TOMORROW MORNING, IT WILL BE DRY
TUESDAY AND BEST CHANCE FOR
SHOWERS OVER THE OCEAN.
FROSTY WEDNESDAY MORNING AND
THURSDAY THE BIGGER STORM COMES
IN WITH GUSTY WINDS AND HEAVY
RAIN.
THIS MORNING IT'S LIGHT RAIN.
COULD BE CAUSING PROBLEMS WITH
THE COMMUTE.
>> SO FAR, SO GOOD.
WE HAVE STANDING WATER AND
PUDDLES, A LOT OF AREAS OF SLICK
ROADS.
PLEASE DO TAKE EXTRA CAUTION.
WE ARE LOOKING AT LIVE SHOT OF
SAN MATEO BRIDGE PAST INDUSTRIAL
LOOKING WESTBOUND WITH
TAILLIGHTS HEADED TOWARD THE
HIGH-RISE.
SERVICING SMOOTH SAILING.
WE TAKE A LOOK AT SAN RAFAEL,
PASSED LUCAS VALLEY ROAD.
FREITAS PARKWAY AND LIGHT
TRAFFIC, STANDING WATER THROUGH
CORTE MADERA AT SIR FRANCIS
DRAKE BOULEVARD.
THERE WAS A PROBLEM ON SILVERADO
TRAIL IN NAPA AREA.
HAD DOWNED POWER LINES AND STILL
BLOCKING THE ROADWAY, PG&E, SO
TRANCAS ROAD WOULD BE THE BEST
BET.
SAN RAMON, A BIG RIG WAS ON
SHOULDER, IT WAS ON FIRE BUT
THAT HAS BEEN OUT SO WE ARE
LOOKING FOR A TOW TRUCK TO
ARRIVE ON THE SCENE.
I DON'T SEE MUCH SLOWING PAST
THE SCENE IN DUBLIN BUT WE'LL
FOLLOW IT FOR YOU.
>>> SIGN OF A CRACK IN THE
FISCAL CLIFF NEGOTIATIONS, BOTH
SIDES MAY BE WILLING TO MAKE A
DEAL.
>> SOUTHWEST SETTLES A CLASS
ACTION LAWSUIT.
FIND OUT WHAT IT WILL
>> Eric: GOOD MONDAY MORNING,
5:14, A LIVE LOOK FROM ROOFTOP
CAMERA.
YOU SEE THE BAY AND BAY BRIDGE
IN THE BACKGROUND.
THERE IS LIGHT RAIN SCATTERED
AROUND THE BAY AREA.
WE WILL SHOW SOME OF THAT TO YOU
AND MIKE WILL SHOW YOU THE
FORECAST WITH LIVE DOPPLER 7-HD.
>> DISCUSSION ABOUT A
CONTROVERSIAL SOCCER FIELD
PROJECT, IT CONTINUES WHEN CITY
COUNCIL MEETS THIS EVENING.
THE PROPOSED PROPERTY IS OPPOSED
BY ENVIRONMENTAL GROUPS AND SOME
RESIDENTS.
CONCERNS INCLUDE THE IMPACT ON
WILDLIFE AND AIRPORT SAFETY
ISSUES.
SUPPORTERS SAY THE CITY NEEDS
MORE ATHLETIC FIELDS.
THE PROJECT IS SUPPORTED BY A
5-1 VOTE FROM THE PLANNING
COMMISSION.
>> SOUTHWEST AIRLINES HAS
SETTLED A LAWSUIT WORTH AN
ESTIMATED $29 MILLION FOR DRINK
VOUCH THERE'S DIDN'T HAVE AN
EXPIRATION DATE.
THE CLASS ACTION SUIT COVERS 6
MILLION UNREDEEMED DRINK
TICKETS.
IT'S WHEN SOUTHWEST CHANGED
THEIR POLICY BECAUSE PEOPLE WERE
ABUSING THE SYSTEM BY USING
PHOTOCOPIES OF THE VOUCHERS.
>>> WITH AMERICA ACCELERATING TO
THE SO-CALLED FISCAL CLIFF.
BUDGET NEGOTIATIONS ARE PICKING
UP MOMENTUM.
JOHN BOEHNER HAS REPORTEDLY
OFFERED A NEW PROPOSAL THAT
WOULD RAISE TAX RATES FOR
EARNERS MAKING MORE THAN A
MILLION.
THE PRESIDENT'S PLAN IS FOR
HIERS RATES ON MORE THAN
$250,000 A YEAR.
POLITICAL ANALYSTS SEE IT AS THE
FIRST STEP TOWARD COMPROMISE.
TAX RATES FOR MOST AMERICANS
WILL GO UP AT THE BEGINNING OF
THE YEAR IF BOTH SIDES DON'T
REACH THE DEAL.
>> Kristen: POST OFFICE IS
GEARING UP FOR THE BUSIEST DAY
OF THE YEAR.
MONDAY IS CHRISTMAS EVE AND BUSY
DAY FALLS TODAY.
LAST DAY TO GET FIRST CLASS MAIL
TO ENSURE THAT IT ARRIVES BY
CHRISTMAS.
THEY EXPECT 800 MILLION PIECES
OF MAIL TO BE HANDLED TODAY,
THAT IS 40% MORE THAN YOUR
AVERAGE DAY.
>> Eric: GET READY FOR MORE SNOW
IN THE SIERRA.
VIDEO SHOT THIS WEEKEND FROM
TAHOE CAM SHOWS SNOW UP THERE
ALREADY.
MORE EXPECTED, SNOW WILL FALL
AND SNOW LEVELS WILL CONTINUE TO
DROP OVER THE NEXT FEW DAYS.
CHECK IT OUT, RIGHT THERE.
VIEWER SENT THIS PHOTO NEAR
MOUNTED CONOCTI NEAR LAKE
PORTED.
>> I THINK YOU NEED CHAIN
CONTROLS IF YOU ARE GOING UP TO
TAHOE.
>> TAHOE WINTER STORM WARNING
IT'S HEAVY THIS MORNING.
YOU NEED CHAINS IF YOU ARE
HEADING UP THAT WAY.
THEY WILL GET A BREAK TUESDAY
AND WEDNESDAY AND THEN HEAVY
SNOW WHILE WE'RE GETTING THE
HEAVY RAIN FOR THURSDAY.
GOOD MORNING.
5:17 ON THE DOT AND COMING OUT
CROSSING A WET GOLDEN GATE
BRIDGE AS YOU COME INTO SAN
FRANCISCO.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT LIVE
DOPPLER 7-HD.
BEST RADAR RETURNS OVER IN NAPA
AND SOLANO, THEY ARE BLUE.
LET'S FOCUS IN ON THE GREEN
WHICH IS NORMALLY SOME HEAVIER
RAIN OR STRONGER RADAR RETURNS.
YOU SEE ALONG MISSION BOULEVARD,
HEADING OVER TO SUNOL GRADE AND
PLEASANTON AND LIVERMORE IS
WHERE WE'RE SEEING THE BEST
RADAR RETURNS AND ALSO ON 238
COMING ACROSS HAYWARD THIS
MORNING.
THERE IS THE LATEST UPDATE.
YOU CAN SEE IT HEADING OVER TO
CALAVARES ROAD AND PIEDMONT
ROAD.
YOU CAN SEE THOSE AREAS WET
ALONG WITH ALUM ROCK.
STEADY RAIN THROUGH THE MORNING
HOURS AND SCATTERED, LIGHT
SHOWERS DURING THE AFTERNOON
HOURS.
TEMPERATURES ARE VERY MILD THIS
MORNING.
HEADING OUT IT'S COOLEST.
CONCORD, 52 DEGREES.
MOUNTAIN VIEW, 56 DEGREES.
MONTEREY BAY, LOW TO MID-50s
WITH LIGHT RAIN FALLING.
MORNING, SLIGHT RAIN AND
SCATTERED SHOWERS DURING THE
AFTERNOON HOURS.
FROSTY TONIGHT AND MORE SO
WEDNESDAY MORNING.
IT COULD BE ONE OF COOLEST
MORNINGS WE'VE HAD THIS SEASON
AND HEAVY RAIN AND GUSTY WINDS
FOR THURSDAY WILL BE MUCH MORE
IMPRESSIVE THAN WHAT WE'RE
DEALING WITH THIS MORNING.
MAIN SYSTEM UP TO THE NORTH,
THAT IS WHERE LOTTO IS STRONGEST
WINDS AND COLD FRONT TRAILING
BEHIND IT.
NOTICE THE COLDER AIR COMING
STRAIGHT DOWN FROM ALASKA ONCE
AGAIN.
THAT IS WHY I THINK WE'LL HAVE
FROST IN THE NEXT COUPLE OF
DAYS.
BEST CHANCE OF STEADY RAIN FROM
NOW THROUGH ABOUT NOON.
THEN IT BECOMES SCATTERED
SHOWERS TO EVEN NOTHING BY THE
EVENING HOURS.
OVERNIGHT, CLOUDS CLEARING OUT
AND COLDER AIR RUSHING IN.
10-20 DEGREES COOLER TOMORROW
MORNING.
BEST CHANCE OF SHOWERS OVER THE
OCEAN TOMORROW AND TEMPERATURES
WILL BE IN THE 30s IN MOST AREAS
WEDNESDAY MORNING.
WE'LL BE IN THE 50s UNDER A
PARTLY SUNNY SKY AND GET READY
FOR THE NEXT SYSTEM.
TUESDAY AND WEDNESDAY TO GET THE
YARD PREPPED.
PERIODS OF RAIN ON FRIDAY.
ANOTHER STORM IS POSSIBLE THIS
COMING WEEKEND.
>> WITH ALL THAT RAIN, WE HAVE
STANDING WATER AND LIKELY A SOLO
SPINOUT IS REALLY BIG.
80 WESTBOUND, RIGHT NEAR GOLDEN
GATE FIELDS.
SOLO SPINOUT.
YOU CAN SEE BUNCHING ON YOUR
SCREEN AS TRAFFIC IS HEADING IN
THE WESTBOUND DIRECTION TOWARD
UNIVERSITY AVENUE.
RAINDROPS AND WET CONDITIONS
HEADING INTO SAN FRANCISCO ON
THE UPPER DECK.
YOU CAN SEE LIGHT TRAFFIC, NO
METERING LIGHTS BUT USE EXTRA
CAUTION.
WE'RE GETTING REPORTS OF VERY
WINDY CONDITIONS, AS WELL.
BART MAY BE A GREAT ALTERNATIVE
FOR YOU.
ON TIME AND CHECKING WITH ALL
MASS TRANSIT AND NO DELAYS
REPORTED.
EVERYBODY IS LOOKING GOOD AT
THIS HOUR.
680 BETWEEN 24 AND 580 JUST OVER
15 MINUTES.
THEN YOUR DRIVE 24 WESTBOUND
CALDECOTT, UNDER 20 MINUTES.
101 SAN RAFAEL STILL UNDER 10
MINUTES.
NOT A BAD RIDE AT 5:20 THIS
MORNING.
>> WHAT A GAME THE NINE ERS
BATTLE BACK AFTER A HUGE LEAD
AGAINST THE PATRIOTS.
>> GIVING BACK THIS HOLIDAY
SEASON, THE GROUP THAT WANTS YOU
TO PASS ON THE RANDOM ACTS OF
KINDNESS.
>> AND THIS AFTERNOON, ON KATIE,
COPING WITH THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL SHOOTING AS THE NATION
TRIES TO UNDERSTAND ARE WE
SERIOUS AT GUN SOLUTIONS.
THAT IS
>>> RAIN CAN FEEL LIKE IT'S
PRETTY WET.
AND LIGHT JACKET THIS MORNING,
DEFINITELY RAIN JACKET.
>> FOOTBALL FAN IS BEING TREATED
AT A MASSACHUSETTS HOSPITAL
AFTER HE FELL OUT OF THE STANDS
AT THE 49ers PATRIOTS GAME LAST
NIGHT.
FAN FELL FROM THE STANDS INTO
THE TUNNEL WHERE THE VISITING
TEAM LEAVES THE FIELD.
MAN WAS ALERT AND AWAKE WHEN HE
LEFT IN AN AMBULANCE.
>> ON THE FIELD THE NINERS
THOUGHT THEY HAD IT UNDER
CONTROL AFTER JUMPING OUT TO
LEAD.
KAEPERNICK WAS SCORED.
THEY SCORED 28 UNANSWERED POINTS
TO TIE THE GAME.
NINERS KEPT IT AND THEY
CORRECTED CAN MICHAEL CRABTREE
AND THE TEAM GOES ON TO PETE
BEAT THE PATRIOTS.
THEY COULD WIN THE N.F.C. TITLE
WITH A WIN IN SEATTLE NEXT
SUNDAY NIGHT.
>>> TOM BRADY, SAN MATEO NATIVE.
GOOD.
WE NEEDED THAT.
5:24.
TALKING ABOUT THE RAIN THIS
MORNING.
NOT VERY HEAVY BUT WITH THE
WIND.
IT FEELS SLOPPY AND COLD.
>> NUISANCE, RIGHT.
>> PAIN TO GET AROUND WITH THAT
WET WEATHER OUT THERE.
TAKE A LOOK AT LIVE DOPPLER,
VERY LIGHT WITH BLUES AND GREENS
BEST RADAR RETURNS AROUND THE
SANTA CRUZ MOUNTAINS WHERE
HEAVIER RAIN FELL DURING THE
OVERNIGHT HOURS.
YOU HAVE SEEN A TAPERING OF
LIGHT RAIN AND DRIZZLE.
HERE IS A LOOK AT MOST OF THE
STATE UNDER THE RADAR.
I THINK NORTH OF BAKERSFIELD AND
FRESNO IS WHERE WE'RE GOING TO
HAVE WET WEATHER FOR MOST OF
DAY.
UPPER 60s DOWN AROUND SAN DIEGO
AND PALM SPRINGS.
WATCH OUT UP IN THE SIERRA IT
WILL BE SNOWING FOR THE BETTER
PART OF TODAY.
>> LIVE SHOT OF 80 BERKELEY WE
ARE WITNESSING A CHP TRAFFIC
BREAK DUE TO THIS EARLIER STALL.
A TOUGH TO SEE BECAUSE OF THE
RAIN BLURRING THE SCREEN BUT
TRAFFIC IS STOPPED RIGHT HERE
PAST GOLDEN GATE FIELDS.
CHP IS SWERVING BACK AND FORTH
TO MAKE SURE THE STALL GETS
CLEARED OUT.
EXPECT DELAYS IN THE AREA.
TRAFFIC IS STOPPED RIGHT NOW.
WE'LL CHECK BACK IN A FEW
MINUTES.
GOLDEN GATE BRIDGE, SOUTHBOUND
CLEAR BUT WET.
USE EXTRA CAUTION THIS MORNING.
A LOT OF SPINOUTS OUT THERE AND
LOTS OF STANDING WATER.
YOU WANT TO TAKE EXTRA CARE.
>> Eric: THANK YOU.
>> Kristen: IN THE HOLIDAY
SEASON AND KIND GESTURE CAN GO A
LONG WAY.
GOOD PEOPLE AT THE OAKLAND
FARMER'S MARKET.
PEOPLE VISITING JACK LONDON
SQUARE WHERE W A KIND WORD
ENCOURAGING THOSE AND FREE HUGS
FROM VOLUNTEERS FROM HAPPINESS
PROJECT.
>> I WAS JUST WALKING BY AND
LOOK AT TOMATOES AND SOMEBODY
GAVE ME THIS NOTE.
AND ASKED ME IF I WANTED A HUG,
I GOT TWO HUGS FROM STRANGERS,
COMPLETE STRANGERS, I THOUGHT
WAS SO HEARTWARMING, WITH ALL
WHAT IS GOING ON AROUND THE
WORLD THESE DAYS.
>> ALONG WITH RANDOM ACTS OF
KINDNESS, IT HELPS PEOPLE WITH
HUNGER, HOUSING AND EMPLOYMENT
NEEDS.
SOME WERE OFFERING THEIR DOG FOR
FREE HUGS.
>>> AS THE NATION COMES TO GRIPS
WITH THE TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT
WE'LL TELL YOU WHAT BAY AREA
SCHOOLS ARE DOING WHAT TEACHERS
ARE READY TO TELL THEM.
>> AND ONE TIGHT SQUEEZE, A MAN
SPENT HIS NIGHT INSIDE AKj;ñ;ñ;ç
>>> GOOD MONDAY MORNING, IT'S
5:29.
WE THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
>> Kristen: I'M KRISTEN SZE.
LET'S START OFF WITH A LOOK AT
TRAFFIC BECAUSE WE HAVE A
PROBLEM ON 80.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
IT WAS A STALL RIGHT PAST GOLDEN
GATE FIELDS WESTBOUND ON 80.
CHP IS DOING A TRAFFIC BREAK.
AS YOU CAN SEE NOW THEY HAVE LET
CARS GO.
YOU CAN EXPECT SOME DELAYS IF
YOU ARE COMING OUT OF RICHMOND
WESTBOUND 80 BUT THAT STALL IS
CLEAR.
FOR NOW TRAFFIC IS MOVING TOWARD
THE MacARTHUR MAZE, ONE QUICK
LOOK AT TOLL PLAZA, IT IS
RAINING AT THE TOLLS BUT TRAFFIC
IS VERY LIGHT ON THE UPPER DECK.
FOR THE LATEST RAINFALL LET'S
CHECK IN WITH MIKE.
>> GOOD MORNING EVERYBODY.
LIGHT RAIN JUST ABOUT EVERYWHERE
THIS MORNING.
LIVE DOPPLER RADAR PICKING UP
BLUES AND GREENS.
THAT IS DRIZZLE TO LIGHT RAIN
THIS MORNING.
BEST CHANCE OF LIGHT RAIN RIGHT
NOW, ACCORDING TO RADAR, HIDDEN
IN THE VALLEYS WE DO HAVE LIGHT
RAIN FALLING.
FREMONT ALL THE WAY DOWN 680 AND
880 INTO MILPITAS, ALUM ROCK AND
EASTERN SECTIONS OF SAN JOSE IS
HEAVIEST RAIN IS FALLING IN THE
SANTA CRUZ MOUNTAINS.
WE'LL HAVE WAVES OF LIGHT RAIN
DURING THE MORNING COMMUTE AND
TEMPERATURES RIGHT NOW IN THE
LOW TO MID 50s.
GUESS WHAT OUR HIGHS ARE IS LOW
TO MID 50s.
>> Eric: IN JUST A FEW HOURS
FIRST FUNERALS WILL BE HELD IN
CONNECTICUT.
PRESIDENT OBAMA PROMISED A CROWD
HE WOULD DO WHATEVER HE COULD TO
MAKE SURE THAT SOMETHING LIKE
THIS DOESN'T HAPPEN AGAIN.
>>> SIX-YEAR-OLD JACK AND NOAL
WILL BE LAID TO REST.
JACK'S FIRST LOVE WAS FOOTBALL
AND NEW YORK GIANTS.
NOAH IS SURVIVED BUT HIS TWIN
SISTER WHO WAS AT THE SCHOOL AT
THE TIME OF THIS SENSELESS
MASSACRE.
HIS FAMILY MEMBERS SAY THEY HAVE
YET TO TELL HIS SIBLINGS HOW HE
PASSED.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SERVED AS
COMFORTER IN CHIEF, MORE THAN
900 MOURNERS, PACKED THE HIGH
SCHOOL AUDITORIUM FOR THE DEEPLY
EMOTIONAL NIGHT.
>> WE OFFER YOU OUR TEARS AND
OUR PAIN, OUR ANGER AND OUR
SORROW.
>> WHATEVER PORTION OF SADNESS
WE CAN SHARE WITH YOU TO EASE
THIS HEAVY LOAD WE WILL GLADLY
BEAR.
>> SOBS WERE HEARD AS HE READ
THE NAMES OF ALL 20 CHILDREN
WHOSE LIVES WERE TAKEN.
AFTER JACK AND NOAH ARE LAID TO
REST THE REST OF THE CHILDREN
WILL BE BURIED LATER THIS WEEK.
NEXT FUNERAL IS SET FOR TOMORROW
FOR JESSICA RAYCOAST.
>>> BY ALL ACCOUNTS THE SHOOTER,
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA KEPT
MOSTLY TO HIMSELF.
NOT MANY PEOPLE KNEW HIM WELL.
THEY SAW NO REASON TO FEAR HIM
BEFORE FRIDAY'S KILLING SPREE.
A NEIGHBOR WHO BABY SAT HIM SAID
HE WAS A QUIET KID.
RYAN CRAFT LIVES IN SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA AND HE NEVER SAW ANY
RED FLAGS.
>> HE WAS REALLY QUIET.
WHENEVER WE DO DOING SOMETHING,
WE WAS REALLY FOCUSED ON IT.
IT WAS LIKE HE WAS IN HIS OWN
WORLD.
>> COMING UP ON "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA", THE MAN WHO MENTORED
ADAM LANZA WILL GIVE HIS AS THE
NATION STILL TRIES TO UNDERSTAND
WHY IT HAPPENED.
>> THIS MORNING, BAY AREA
STUDENTS ARE GOING BACK TO
SCHOOL FOR THE FIRST TIME SINCE
THE NATIONAL TRAGEDY.
AMY HOLLYFIELD IS LIVE AT LAKE
SHORE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN SAN
FRANCISCO.
WILL STUDENTS NOTICE A
DIFFERENCE?
>> AT THIS SCHOOL THE TEACHERS
ARE GOING TO GET SOME HELP.
TEACHERS' UNION SENT OUT AN
E-MAIL WITH A GUIDE TO HELP
STEER THE CONVERSATION SO THEY
WILL LIKELY BE HAVING WITH
STUDENTS.
THEY ARE EXPECTING QUESTIONS.
THEY ARE EXPECTING CONCERNS FROM
KIDS AS THEY HEAD BACK TO SCHOOL
TODAY.
THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNION SAYS
HE THINKS THAT TALK IS GOOD.
>> THEY ARE HELPED BY HONESTLY
TALKING ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO HAVE THE
ANSWER BUT YOU HAVE TO GIVE THE
CHILD AN OUTLET.
IF YOU ARE CONCERNED ABOUT YOUR
CHILD'S BEHAVIOR, SEEK OUT A
PEDIATRICIAN OR ANOTHER
CAREGIVER.
SPEAK OUT PROFESSIONAL.
WHAT THE CHILDREN ARE LOOKING TO
ADULTS IN THEIR LIVES AS PARENTS
AND TEACHERS TO GIVE THEM
GUIDANCE.
>> STATE CALIFORNIA EMERGENCY
MANAGEMENT AGENCY OFFERS TIPS ON
THE WEBSITE, KNOW YOUR SCHOOL'S
EMERGENCY ACTION PLAN AND KNOW
YOUR ALERT SYSTEM FOR PARENTS
AND CREATE OR REVIEW YOUR
FAMILY'S ACTION PLAN.
IF YOU ARE AREN'T FAMILIAR WITH
ALL THESE PLANS, TODAY IS A GOOD
DAY TO START LEARNING AND ASKING
QUESTIONS ABOUT THEM.
SCHOOLS WILL BE EXPECTING A LOT
OF QUESTIONS TODAY.
IT'S GOING TO BE A DAY OF
REITERATING AND REINFORCEMENT.
>> Terry: WEEKEND WAS FILLED
WITH MEMORIALS WHO REMEMBER THE
VICTIMS OF THE SANDY HOOK
SHOOTING HERE IN THE BAY AREA.
IN SAN FRANCISCO, ST. MARY'S
CATHEDRAL DEDICATED REGULAR MASS
TO THE FAMILIES IN CONNECTICUT
AND TO THOSE IN PAIN ACROSS THE
COUNTRY.
NUMEROUS VIGILS AND TRIBUTES
WERE HELD AS PEOPLE HERE TRY TO
COME TO TERMS WITH THE TRAGEDY.
TONIGHT AT 7:00 THEY WILL BE A
SERVICE OF REMEMBRANCE ON THE
PENINSULA.
IT WILL TAKE PLACE AT FIRST
PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH IN
BURLINGAME ON EASTON DRIVE.
>> JOE LEEB ER MAN WANTS A
COMMISSION TO REVIEW NATIONAL
GUN LAWS AND MENTAL HEALTH
SYSTEM TO RECOMMEND CHANGES.
HE WANTS TO CLOSE LOOPHOLES TO
ALLOW GUN BUYERS TO AVOID
BACKGROUND CHECKS.
DEMOCRATIC SENATOR FEINSTEIN
WILL CALL FOR A VOTE ON AN
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN THE FIRST
DAY THAT CONGRESS IS BACK IN
SESSION.
>> IT WILL BAN THE SALE THE
TRANSFER AND THE POSSESSION NOT
RETRO AGOIVELY BUT PROSPECTIVELY
AND WILL BAN THE SAME FOR BIG
CLIP DRUMS OR STRIPS OF MORE
THAN TEN BULLETS.
>> THE SENATOR, OF COURSE, FROM
THE SAN FRANCISCO AREA, GUN
RIGHTS GROUPS HAVE REMAINED
SILENCE SINCE THE SHOOTING
SPREE.
NATIONAL RIFLE ASSOCIATION
REMOVED A TWEET POSTED ONE DAY
BEFORE WHICH CELEBRATED 1.7
MILLION LIKES ON FACEBOOK.
>>> ACTIVIST GROUP ANONYMOUS IS
RENEWING ITS ATTACK ON BAT
BAPTIST CHURCH AFTER THE CHURCH
PRAISED THE ACTIONS OF SHOOT
THEY ARE THE CONNECTICUT
SHOOTING MASSACRE.
THEY WILL PICKET SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY THAT GOD'S WILL IS
PUNISHING AMERICANS FOR
SUPPORTING GAY MARRIAGE.
>>> "ABC 7 NEWS" WILL CONTINUE
TO COVER THIS STORY AS IT
UNFOLDS AND FIND THE LATEST
DEVELOPMENTS ON OUR WEBSITE AT
ABC7NEWS.COM AS WELL AS OUR
FACEBOOK PAGE AND OUR TWITTER
FEEDS.
>> Kristen: SEEMS LIKE WEATHER
IS REFLECTING THE MOOD.
>> WE STARTED WITH SOME LIGHT
RAIN EVEN SOME DRIZZLE AND
BREEZY AT TIMES WITH WINDS UP TO
AROUND 10-15 MILES AN HOUR.
YOU SEE ON DOPPLER RADAR THAT WE
HAVE THE SATELLITE AND RADAR
RETURNS.
WE DO HAVE LIGHT RAIN JUST ABOUT
EVERYWHERE THIS MORNING.
LIGHTED BLUE SAYS INDICATIVE TO
THE LIGHT RAIN.
DEEPER MOISTURE ON WATER VAPOR
IMAGERY.
DRIER AIR IN THE FORM OF ORANGE
AS WE HEAD INTO THE AFTERNOON
HOURS.
STEADY LIGHT RAIN THIS MORNING
AND FEW SHOWERS AROUND NOON AND
ISOLATED SHOWER BY 4:00.
NOTICE OUR TEMPERATURES ARE IN
THE LOW TO MID 50s NOW AND LOW
TO MID 50s THROUGH THE AFTERNOON
HOURS.
CLEARING WILL START IN THE
EVENING HOURS AND TEMPERATURES
WILL DROP QUICKLY.
YOU WILL NEED A HEAVIER COAT.
MAINLY DRY, BEST CHANCE OF A
SHOWER OVER THE OCEAN ON TUESDAY
LOW TO MID 50s.
MID-50s ON WEDNESDAY BUT THAT IS
AFTER A FROSTY START.
MOST OF US WILL START IN THE 30s
AND EVEN A FEW 20s INLAND AND
STRONG STORM WITH DUSTY WINDS
AND TEMPERATURES ONCE AGAIN IN
THE LOW TO MID-50s.
>> GOOD MORNING.
SO FAR, SO GOOD.
HEAVY TRAFFIC OUT OF RICHMOND
DUE TO AN EARLIER STALL.
WE SAW THE CHP DOING A TRAFFIC
BREAK.
HAD EVERYTHING MOMENTARILY
HALTED BEFORE UNIVERSITY BUT
THINGS ARE FLOWING AGAIN ALBEIT
HEAVY INTO THE MacARTHUR MAZE.
THIS IS NORTH 87 AND WE DO GET
FLOODING IN THIS AREA RIGHT PAST
HP PAVILION.
WE'LL KEEP OUR EYE ON THAT SO
FAR, SO GOOD.
COMING OFF THE WALDO GRADE,
BRIDGE PATROL IS TELLING US
THERE IS SOME MUD IN THE RIGHT
LANES AS YOU APPROACH THE GOLDEN
GATE BRIDGE.
TRAFFIC IS FLOWING NICELY.
ALL FOUR LANES ARE OPEN FOR
SOUTHBOUND COMMUTE.
>>> A QUIET DRIVE TURNS INTO A
DEADLY ACCIDENT IN THE EAST BAY.
NEXT, ONLY ON 7, IT WAS ALMOST
DEADLY I SHOULD SAY.
FRIGHTENING SCENE BEFORE
FIREFIGHTERS GOT THERE.
>> AND STEPPING OUT THE DUCHESS
OF CAMBRIDGE MAKES HER FIR
♪ WE WERE SKIPPING STONES
AND LETTING GO ♪
♪ OVER THE RIVER
AND DOWN THE ROAD ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
AT NATURE VALLEY,
WE KNOW NATURE COMES TOGETHER
IN AMAZING WAYS.
THAT'S WHY WE BRING TOGETHER
NATURAL INGREDIENTS,
LIKE DARK CHOCOLATE
WITH TOASTED OATS,
OR SWEET GOLDEN HONEY.
PERFECT COMBINATIONS OF
NATURE'S DELICIOUS INGREDIENTS,
FROM NATURE VALLEY.
♪
♪ I WAS THINKING
THAT I HOPE THIS NEVER ENDS ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA BARS,
NATURE AT ITS MOST DELICIOUS.
>> Eric: GOOD MORNING, 5:42,
LIVE SHOT FROM THE ROOFTOP
CAMERA TOWARDS SAN FRANCISCO.
YOU CAN SEE THE FERRY BUILDING,
BAY BRIDGE, YOU CAN SEE THE WET
ROADS.
THERE IS RAIN OUT THERE.
>>> NEW THIS MORNING, SAN
FRANCISCO FIREFIGHTERS RESCUED A
MAN THAT WAS STUCK IN A CHIMNEY
OVERNIGHT.
IT HAPPENED AROUND MIDNIGHT AT
SIX-STORY BUILDING IN THE LAUREL
HEIGHTS NEIGHBORHOOD.
RESCUE CAUSED QUITE A COMMOTION
FOR PEOPLE LIVING THERE.
THEY DON'T KNOW WHY HE WAS IN
THE CHIMNEY AND THEY HAD TO
LOOSEN SEVERAL BRICKS TO GET HIM
OUT.
>> THIS MORNING, ALAMEDA COUNTY
SHERIFF'S DEPUTIES ARE
INVESTIGATING A FATAL COLLISION
BETWEEN A PEDESTRIAN AND TRAIN
NEAR HAYWARD.
IT HAPPENED NEAR THE
INTERSECTION OF WEST BLOSSOM
LANE AND TIMES AVENUE AROUND
7:00 LAST NIGHT.
THE TRACKS WERE SHUT DOWN WHILE
AUTHORITIES INVESTIGATED THE
NAMES OF THE VICTIM HAS NOT BEEN
RELEASED.
>> THE HIGHWAY PATROL IS
INVESTIGATING A FIERY ACCIDENT
IN ORINDA.
DRIVER LOST CONTROL OF THE
VEHICLE AS HE WAS EXITING
HIGHWAY 24.
CAR FLIPPED AND CAUGHT FIRE.
NEWS REPORTER ALAN WANG SHOT
THIS VIDEO.
HE WAS THERE MOMENTS BEFORE THE
FIRE DEPARTMENT ARRIVED.
DRIVER AND PASSENGER GOT OUT
SAFELY.
>> AUTHORITIES IN CONTRA COSTA
ARE INVESTIGATING A RAPE ON A
POPULAR HIKING TRAIL.
WOMAN SAID SHE WAS ATTACKED ON
THE MA DRONE TRAIL IN ALAMO.
SHE SAYS HER ATTACKER WAS IN HIS
EARLY 40s AND WALKING A HEAVY
SET DOG.
IT HAPPENED LAST WEDNESDAY
AFTERNOON.
THEY SAY THE ATTACKER GRABBED
HER BY THE HAIR AND PULLED HER
TO THE GROUND BEFORE RAPING HER.
>> TODAY THE SAN FRANCISCO FIRE
DEPARTMENT AND OTHER BAY AREA
AGENCIES WILL TRY TO KEEP IT
FROM HAPPENING TO YOU.
THIS MORNING THEY WILL
INTENTIONALLY SET A DRIED OUT
CHRISTMAS TREE ON FIRE TO SHOW
IT TAKES A FEW SECONDS TO TURN
YOUR HOME TO A DEATH TRAP.
A FEW SAFETY PRECAUTIONS DON'T
LEAVE A LIVE TREE UP FOR LONGER
THAN TWO WEEKS.
GET A STAND FILLED WITH WATER AT
THE BASE AND DON'T PUT YOUR TREE
NEAR HEAT SOURCES.
>> TIME IS RUNNING OUT IF YOU
WANT TO SHIP YOUR HOLIDAY GIFT
FOR FREE.
>> HERE IS JANE KING.
>> GOOD MORNING.
PUSH FOR STRONGER GUN CONTROL IS
ON AFTER THE TRAGIC KILLINGS IN
CONNECTICUT.
DIANNE FEINSTEIN PLANS MORE
EFFORTS TO MONTH MOVE A BAN ON
ASSAULT WEAPONS.
DICK DURBIN PROMISING TO HOLD
HEARINGS ON GUN RIGHTS BUT MANY
REPUBLICANS AND DEMOCRATS OPPOSE
GUN REGULATION AND CONGRESS IS
UNLIKELY TO PASS NEW GUN CONTROL
LEGISLATION SOON BECAUSE THE
FOCUS IS RIGHT NOW ON BUDGET
MATTERS.
>> MEANTIME, FISCAL CLIFF TALKS.
HOUSE SPEAKER HAS AGREED TO
RAISE TAXES ON HOUSEHOLDS I
THINK MORE THAN MILLION DOLLARS
A YEAR IF PRESIDENT OBAMA AGREES
TO CUT ENTITLEMENT PROGRAMS.
ONLINE RETAILERS GEARING UP FOR
A BUSY DAY.
FLEE SHIPPING DAY, LAST DAY TO
ARRIVE BEFORE CHRISTMAS.
>>> IT'S 5:46.
LIGHT RAIN IN THE BAY AREA.
>> JUST ABOUT EVERYBODY,
EVERYBODY IS GETTING MOIST.
WE TAKE A LOOK AT, YOU SEE A FEW
DROPS AS WE LOOK TOWARD THE
SOUTH.
EMBARCADERO CENTER AND THE
BRIDGE.
IT'S NOT TOO HEAVY, A MILE AWAY
FROM WHERE WE ARE THE LIVE
DOPPLER 7-HD, THAT IS SOME
DRIZZLE AND POSSIBLY LIGHT RAIN
WHERE WE SEE SOME GREEN UP TO 80
APPROACHING VALLEJO AND OVER THE
SANTA CRUZ MOUNTAINS.
WE SEE PULLING AWAY FROM NAPA
AND HEADING TOWARD GREEN VALLEY
ROAD AND ALSO WOODEN VALLEY ROAD
HEADING INTO 80 WHERE IT IS MORE
OF A VALLEY WHERE WE'RE SEEING
OUR BEST RADAR RETURNS.
HEADING DOWN TO THE SOUTH, SAN
MATEO WE'RE LOOKING HAYWARD
STREET, HOWARD STREET, EXCUSE
ME.
FREMONT, SAME AREA, COMING OUT
OF THE SUNOL GRADE INTO 880 AND
680 TOWARD MILPITAS.
BIG PICTURE, YOU CAN SEE
EVERYBODY GETTING NICKEL AND
DIMED BY LIGHT RAIN AND SNOW
FALLING IN THE SIERRA.
SIX HOUR RAIN TOTALS, A QUARTER
OF AN INCH IN SANTA ROSA WHERE
THE RAIN CAME IN FIRST BUT THE
TAPERING CONSIDERING JUST COUPLE
INCHES AROUND SAN FRANCISCO AND
OAKLAND AND CONCORD.
HAYWARD AND SAN JOSE, NOTHING IN
MEASURABLE.
LOW TO MID 50s AND HIMSELF
AROUND THE MONTEREY BAY.
STEADY LIGHT RAIN THROUGH THE
MORNING HOURS.
SCATTERED SHOWERS IN THE
AFTERNOON HOURS.
FROSTY TONIGHT AND MORE SO
WEDNESDAY NIGHT.
THEN HEAVY RAIN AND GUSTY WINDS,
BIG STORM COMING IN FOR THURSDAY
LOW PRESSURE -- I'M JOKING.
WE'RE FORECASTING PAST THE 21,
WE DON'T BELIEVE IN THE MAYANS.
HERE IS A LOOK THE SHOWERS FOR
NOON AND THEN YOU CAN SEE HOW IT
CLEARS OUT CONSIDERABLY BY 5:00.
AS WE HEAD OVERNIGHT INTO
TOMORROW MORNING, 30s INLAND
VALLEYS, 40s ELSEWHERE.
STORM TRACKS OVER THE OCEAN.
BEST CHANCE OF SHOWERS, ANOTHER
REINFORCING SHOT OF COLD AIR,
TUESDAY NIGHT INTO WEDNESDAY
MORNING, WE'RE GOING TO HAVE 20s
INLAND, 30s FOR THE REST OF US.
BY THE TIME WE GET TO THAT
AFTERNOON, HIGH CLOUDS AND
SUNSHINE AND TEMPERATURES IN THE
MID-50s.
STRONGER STORM COMING IN
THURSDAY AND ANOTHER STORM FOR
SATURDAY THAT WILL LINGER INTO
SUNDAY.
IT WILL BE VERY STORMY THURSDAY,
FRIDAY, SATURDAY AND SUNDAY.
>> LIVE SHOT OF THE BAY BRIDGE
TOLL PLAZA, YOU CAN SEE RAIN AND
CARS DRIVING IN.
MINOR BACK-UP FOR PAYING CASH
BUT THEY ARE PICKING UP A LOT OF
STANDING WATER AS YOU APPROACH
THE BAY BRIDGE.
PROBLEM IN SUNNYVALE, EARLIER
SOLO SPINOUT, BEHIND THAT A
MAJOR ACCIDENT NOW AS WELL AS
THIS.
THE RED LINE STRETCHES FROM
MATILDA WITH THE SERIOUS
ACCIDENT IN THE TWO LEFT LANES
AND ONE OF OUR ABC TRAFFIC
SPOTTERS SENDING IN PHOTOGRAPH
SHOWING BUMPER-TO-BUMPER TRAFFIC
IN NORTHBOUND DIRECTION.
IF YOU WANT TO DOWNLOAD THIS APP
IT'S A FREE APP, GO TO
ABC7NEWS.COM FOR MORE POSITION
AT APPLE APP STORE TO NAVIGATE
YOUR COMMUTE WHICH IS A WET ONE
THIS MORNING.
>> SUE, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
KANSAS PLACE ARE SEARCHING FOR A
SUSPECT WANTED FOR SHOOTING AND
KILLING TWO OF THEIR OFFICERS.
THE SHOOTING OUTSIDE A GROCERY
STORE IN TOPEKA AND TWO OFFICERS
WERE RESPONDING TO A REPORTED OF
A SUSPICIOUS VEHICLE.
INVESTIGATORS FOUND THE CAR TEN
BLOCKS AWAY.
THEY SEARCHED THE HOUSE BUT DID
NOT FIND THE SUSPECT.
>> PERSON IS RECOVERING AFTER
AUTHORITIES IN TEXAS SAY A
GUNMAN OPENED FIRE AT A SAN
ANTONIO MOVIE THEATER PARKING
LOT.
HE BEGIN SHOOTING AND LUCKILY NO
ONE WAS HIT.
THE SHERIFF'S DEPARTMENT SAYS AN
OFF-DUTY DEPUTY WORKING SECURITY
SPOTTED THE GUNMAN AND SHOT HIM.
NO WORD ON A POSSIBLE MOTIVE OR
THE CONDITION OF THE ACCUSED
GUNMAN.
>>> IN AFGHANISTAN A BOMB KILLED
TEN YOUNG GIRLS IN EASTERN PART
OF THE COUNTRY.
IT HAPPENED IN A PROVINCE ABOUT
HUNDRED MILES EAST OF THE
CAPITAL CITY OF KABIL.
TEN VICTIMS RANGE IN AGE FROM 9
TO 13.
TWO OTHER GIRLS WERE IN CRITICAL
CONDITION.
AN AFGHAN OFFICIAL SAYS THE
GIRLS WERE GATHERING FIREWOOD
WHEN THE BOMB EXPLODED.
>> THE DUCHESS OF CAMBRIDGE MADE
HER FIRST PUBLIC APPEARANCE
SINCE HER RECENT
HOSPITALIZATION.
ONLOOKERS THE DUCHESS SEEMED
COMPOSED AND COMFORTABLE.
SHE AND HER HUSBAND IS EXPECTING
THEIR FIRST CHILD.
THE DUCHESS WAS HOSPITALIZED FOR
ACUTE MORNING SICKNESSES.
>> KEYING AN EYE ON THE SKY.
WHY BERKELEY WANTS TO KEEP
SURVEILLANCE DRONES OUT OF ITS
AIRSPACE.
>> AND DIET PEPSI
>>> WELCOME BACK.
5:54, YOU CAN SEE WAVES OF LIGHT
RAIN NOT ONLY HERE BUT AS YOU
HEAD UP TO THE SIERRA.
SUE TELLS ME YOU NEED CHAINS ON
ALL THE HIGHWAYS THERE.
MOST OF US IN THE 50s UNTIL YOU
GET DOWN TO SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA,
MID TO UPPER 60s THERE.
LET'S HEAD TO THE SIERRA, WINTER
STORM WARNING FOR THE WESTERN
SLOPE AS YOU HEAD INTO LAKE
TAHOE.
MOST OF THE SNOW IS FALLING ON
THE WESTERN SLOPE.
GUSTY WINDS B OUT OF SOUTHEAST.
>> TROUBLE SPOTS, SUNNYVALE,
NORTH 101 BEFORE MATILDA, SOLO
SPIN SWROUT BEHIND THAT TWO CAR
ACCIDENT IN THE TWO LEFT LANES.
TAKING A LOOK AT WAZE APP, VERY
SLOW.
TRAFFIC SPOTTERS A COMPLETE
STAND STILL TOWARD THE LAWRENCE
EXPRESSWAY NORTHBOUND 101.
IF YOU WANT TO DOWNLOAD THIS APP
IT IS FREE.
ONCE AGAIN EXPECT DELAYS FROM
SAN JOSE UP TOWARDS SUNNYVALE.
>>> RICHMOND CITY OFFICIALS MEET
TOMORROW TO CONSIDER PERMITS FOR
RECONSTRUCTION OF THE DAMAGED
PORTION OF THE CHEVRON REFINERY.
A PIPELINE RUPTURED IN AUGUST
CAUSING AN EXPLOSION AND FIRE.
THIS MORNING SAN FRANCISCO
CHRONICLE CHEVRON WILL HAVE TO
LAY OFF 600 WORKERS IF IT
DOESN'T GET THE PERMITS BY
THURSDAY.
THE COMPANY WANTS TO REPLACE THE
DESTROYED PIPE WITH A METAL
ALLOY CRITICS ARE PRESSURING
THEM TO USE STAINLESS STEEL.
CORROSION IS CONSIDERED LIKELY
CAUSE OF THE EXPLOSION.
>> MORE THAN 90 MILLION
AMERICANS WILL TRAVEL MORE THAN
50 MILES THIS SEASON AND 90% OF
THEM WILL DO IT ON THE ROAD.
GAS PRICES CONTINUE TO FALL.
IN CALIFORNIA COSTS 3.62 A
GALLON DOWN 23 CENTS FROM
MID-NOVEMBER.
BAY AREA, AVERAGE PRICE IS 3.71
PER GALLON.
THE MOST EXPENSIVE IS IN SAN
FRANCISCO AT 3.83.
VALLEJO HAS THE CHEAPEST PRICES,
3.49 PER GALLON.
>> IN BERKELEY, THEY WILL
CONSIDER A PROPOSAL TOMORROW TO
DECLARE THE AIR A NO DRONE ZONE.
THEY REPORT BERKELEY'S PEACE AND
JUSTICE COMMISSION FEARS
AUTHORITIES WILL USE THE
TECHNOLOGY TO SPY ON CITIZENS.
THIS PROPOSAL COMES A WEEK AFTER
ALAMEDA COUNTY SUPERVISORS
TABLED THE PLAN BY THE SHERIFF'S
DEPARTMENT TO SPEND $31,000
GRANT TO BUY A SURVEILLANCE
DRONE.
THEY CAME UNDER PRESSURE BY
PRIVACY ADVOCATES.
>>> DIET PEPSI TASTING SWEETER
TO YOU LATELY, YOUR TASTE BUDS
ARE RIGHT ON.
THIS NEW DIET PEPSI FORMULA
CONTAINS A SWEETENER AND THE
CHANGE IS DESIGNED TO HELP THE
SODA FROM DEGRADING.
THEY ARE REIG TO REINVIGORATE
THEIR BRAND.
PEPSI WILL LAUNCH A NEW
REBRANDING CAMPAIGN.
YOU CAN SEE THE NEW INGREDIENT
LISTED ON THE CAN AND IT WILL BE
INTERESTING TO SEE WHAT PEOPLE'S
RESPONSE WILL BE.
>>> NEXT AT 6:00, BACK ON THE
STORM WATCH, MIKE NICCO IS
TRACKING THE SHOWERS HITTING THE
BAY AREA RIGHT NOW WITH LIVE
DOPPLER 7-HD.
>> ALSO AHEAD, SAYING GOODBYE,
THE FUNERALS TAKING PLACE TODAY
FOR THE YOUNG VICTIMS OF THE
SANDY HOOK TRAGEDY AND CAL
>>> A NEW STORM HAS ARRIVED IN
THE BAY AREA BUT A LARGER STORM
IS ON THE WAY.
>> FIRST FUNERAL IN SAND NEWTOWN
IS UNDER WAY.
>> AND STUDENTS WILL RETURN TO
BAY AREA AND WE'LL LEARN MORE
ABOUT THE SAFETY PLANS THAT ARE
NOW UNDERWAY.
>> THANKS FOR JOINING US.
>> I'M ERIC THOMAS.
LET'S GET A LOOK AT THE WEATHER
WE WERE SHOWING YOU ON LIVE
DOPPLER 7-HD.
IS IT RAINING ACROSS THE BAY
AREA.
>> PRETTY MUCH.
A LOT OF US ARE RECEIVING RAIN,