DISGUSTED, BUT MOST OF ALL,
EXTREMELY SAD.
LeBRON JAMES TWEETING, ONCE
AGAIN, OUR COUNTRY IS GOING
THROUGH ANOTHER HORRIFIC
TRAGEDY.
PRAYERS GO OUT TO ALL OF THE
FAMILIES IN CONNECTICUT.
I'M SICK.
>>> AND ROBERT GRIFFIN III, I
MAY NOT BE A PARENT BUT I CANNOT
BEGIN TO IMAGINE HOW IT FEELS TO
HAVE MY CHILD'S LIFE TAKEN AWAY.
AND NO ONE EVER SHOULD.
>>> LAST NIGHT, NBA ARENAS BEGAN
THEIR GAMES WITH A MOMENT OF
SILENCE.
>> PLEASE JOIN US IN OBSERVING A
MOMENT OF SILENCE IN ON NOR OF
THE VICTIMS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
>> THAT SCENE PLAYING OUT ACROSS
THE LEAGUE LAST NIGHT.
TODAY, IN NEW YORK GIANTS
ANNOUNCING THEY'LL WEAR SPECIAL
DECALS TO HONOR THE VICTIMS FOR
THEIR GAME TOMORROW AGAINST THE
ATLANTA FALCONS.
>>> FOR THE LATEST ON THIS
TRAGEDY, GO TO ABCNEWS.COM.
UPDATES WILL CONTINUE THROUGHOUT
THE DAY HERE ON ABC AS WELL.
>>> ONE BIT OF HEADLINES FROM
THE SPORTING NEWS TODAY.
RAY LEWIS NOT PLAYING TOMORROW
AGAINST THE RAVENS AGAINST THE
BRONCOS.
THAT, ACCORDING TO OUR SAL
PAOLANTONIO AND ADAM SHEFTER.
LEWIS STILL RECOVERING FROM A
TORN TRICEPS SUFFERED EARLIER IN
THE SEASON.
>>> I'LL BE BACK IN AN HOUR WITH
A PREVIEW OF A GREAT WEEKEND IN
THE NFL AND A LOOK AT THE
SHOCKING SEASON THUS FAR FOR THE
L.A. LAKERS.
BUT FIRST, HERE'S S.E.C. STORY
CREW, ENJOY.
>>> THE FOLLOWING IS A SPECIAL
PRESENTATION OF S.E.C. ON ESPN.
>>> STORIED COACHES.
STORIED MOMENTS.
STORIED GAMES.
>> CRACKED BY REGGIE WHITE!
>> STORIED PLAYERS.
>> WELCOME TO THE PREMIER.
ERA OF GRIDIRON FOOTBALL.
>> IT TAKES TEN TO CHANGE THE
CULTURE.
>> THAT'S WHAT THE GAME IS
ABOUT.
>> THERE'S ONLY ONE COLOR IN
MADISON AND THAT COLOR IS
MAROON.
>> THE S.E.C. IS STORIED.
♪
>> I WAS TAUGHT AT HOME,
WHATEVER TALENT YOU HAVE, USE IT
FOR GOD.
>> HE SAID, SONS, IF YOU DIG A
DITCH, YOU DIG THE BEST DITCH.
YOU DIG IT BECAUSE IT'S THE
RIGHT THING TO DO.
>> STRIVE TO BE PERFECT, KNOWING
THAT YOU'RE NOT GOING TO REACH
PERFECTION.
BUT IN THE EFFORT TO BE PERFECT,
IN THE EFFORT TO BE THE BEST YOU
MAXIMIZE WHATEVER ABILITY GOD
HAS GIVEN YOU.
>> THAT SERMON I PREACH,
PREACHERS, IS NOT THE RUN HERE
ON SUNDAY MORNING.
IT IS THE ONE THAT I LIVE EACH
AND EVERY DAY THE BEST SONG YOU
SING IS NOT HERE BUT IT'S ON
MONDAY, TUESDAY, WEDNESDAY,
THURSDAY AND FRIDAY.
SATURDAY AND SUNDAY.
>> YOU'RE ALWAYS TRYING TO PROVE
YOURSELF.
AND REALLY HAS BEEN THAT WAY
EVER SINCE THE SLAVES GOT OFF
THE SHIP FROM JAMESTOWN.
YOU HAVE TO PROVE THAT YOU WERE
A PART OF THE FABRIC OF AMERICAN
LIFE.
AS BLACK MAN, YOU AND YOUR
ANCESTORS WERE PART OF BUILDING
THIS GREAT COUNTRY.
AND HAVING TO EARN YOUR WAY INTO
A POSITION WHERE YOU WERE
RESPECTED AS AN EQUAL.
AND IT'S BEEN THAT WAY FOR
YEARS.
>>> YOU'RE AWARE THAT THE CIVIL
RIGHTS MOVEMENT HAS STARTED.
THAT'S WHEN IT SEEMED LIKE
SOMETHING WAS HAPPENING EVERY
SINGLE NIGHT.
IT WAS LIKE THE WORLD WAS BEING
TURNED UPSIDE-DOWN.
I WAS BORN IN '54, SO, IN THE
EARLY '60s, I'M 7, 8 AND 9 YEARS
OLD.
I KNEW WE RODE ON THE BACK OF
THE BUS.
I KNEW THAT WE WENT TO THE
BATHROOMS THAT HAD "COLORED" ON
IT.
I KNEW WE DRANK OUT OF FOUNTAINS
THAT HAD "COLORED" ON IT.
I KNEW THAT SOMETHING WAS NOT
RIGHT., VED IN HOPE, ALABAMA,
WHICH WAS SORT OF THE HAVEN FOR
THE KU KLUX KLAN.
MY PARENTS GREW UP WITH SONS
THAT WERE MEMBERS OF THE KLAN.
THEY CALLED MY DAD SUGAR, THEY
RESPECTED HIM AND THEY WERE
LIKE, SUG, NOTHING IS GOING TO
HAPPEN TO YOU.
>> IT WAS CHALLENGING THAT THERE
WERE PEOPLE THAT WERE BEEN
TORTURED AROUND THE COUNTRY.
PEOPLE WERE COMING UP MISSING.
BUT, OUR FAITH IS WHAT KEPT US
DRIVEN TO KNOW THAT IT'S GOING
TO BE BETTER.
>> ALL YOU KNOW IS THAT THE
CHANGE IS HAPPENING.
WE GOT SITTINS.
DR. KING, ALL THE STUDENTS ARE
MARCHING.
THIS IS SO THAT WE CAN HAVE THE
SAME RIGHTS THAT EVER OTHER
CITIZEN IN THIS COUNTRY.
THAT'S WHAT I UNDERSTOOD.
BUT WHEN THE 16th STREET BOMBING
HAPPENED, YOU KNOW, THAT TESTED
MY NONVIOLENCE THEORY REALLY,
REALLY HARD.
FOR A LOT OF PEOPLE.
IT WAS JUST SO SHOCKING.
THAT YOU COULD BE SITTING IN
CHURCH ON A SUNDAY MORNING,
WORSHIPING GOD, AND THAT
HAPPENED?
THOSE GIRLS DIDN'T DO ANYTHING
TO ANYBODY.
THEY WERE JUST GOING TO CHURCH.
YOU KNOW?
THAT ONE -- THAT ONE WAS HARD.
♪
>> HE NEVER NEEDED ANYONE TO
REMIND HIM OF HOW UNFAIR LIFE
COULD BE, HE ALWAYS KNEW HOW
HARD, HOW PAINFUL AND HOW
IMPERFECT PROGRESS WAS.
AS A BOY, THE REMINDERS WERE ALL
AROUND HIM.
AND THE LESSONS CAME FROM THE
MAN THAT HE WAS NAMED FOR.
YOU SEE, EVERY SUNDAY, SYLVESTER
CROOM JR. WENT TO CHURCH AND
EVERY SUNDAY, HE LISTENED TO HIS
FATHER PREACH ABOUT THE WORLD
THEY FOUND THEMSELVES IN AND
WHAT IT WOULD TAKE TO CHANGE IT.
>> DADDY WAS PREACHING DR.
KING'S MANTRA OF NONVIOLENCE.
THAT LOVE WOULD CONQUER.
AND YOU COULD NOT DEFEAT
VIOLENCE WITH VIOLENCE.
HE WAS A JOYFUL MAN.
HE GREETED EVERYONE WITH A
SMILE.
HE ALWAYS HAD A KIND WORD TO
SAY, A MAN OF HIS WORD, THAT WAS
BIG WITH HIM, HONOR, INTEGRITY,
CHARACTER.
HE DEMANDED EXCELLENCE.
BUT NOT IN A HARSH WAY.
AS A FATHER, AS A HUSBAND --
JUST AS A MAN, HE IS WITHOUT
QUESTION MY ROLE MODEL, THAT'S
WHAT I JUDGE MYSELF BY, BY HIM.
♪
THE FIRST TIME I WENT TO AN
INTEGRATED SCHOOL, IN ALL OF MY
CLASSES, I WAS THE ONLY BLACK
STUDENT THERE.
YOUR CONDUCT WAS ALWAYS UNDER
EXAMINATION, HOW YOU DRESSED --
HOW YOU -- EVERS A -- EVERY
ASPECT OF IT.
YOU WERE REPRESENTING NOT ONLY
YOURSELF BUT YOU WERE
REPRESENTING ALL OF THE BLACK
STUDENTS.
WE WERE ALSO COACHED UP TO
UNDERSTAND THAT IT WAS A
NONVIOLENT CHANGE.
NOW IN THE RACIAL STRUGGLE,
OKAY, IN THE CIVIL RIGHTS
MOVEMENT, OKAY, YEAH, IT'S
NONVIOLENT.
WE WALK AWAY.
YOU DON'T RETALIATE.
VERBALLY OR PHYSICALLY.
BUT ON A FOOTBALL FIELD, THAT'S
THE GREAT EQUALIZER.
NOW I GET TO HIT ANYTHING THAT
MOVES.
YOU LINE UP ACROSS A GUY, HE
HITS YOU AND YOU HIT HIM, WHAT
COLOR YOU ARE THAT DON'T MATTER
VERY OFTEN.
YOU MAY NEVER LIKE EACH OTHER
AND YOU MAY HAVE A DIFFERENCE OF
OPINION ABOUT THINGS.
BUT THE FIRST THING THAT HAS TO
BE ESTABLISHED IN ANY
RELATIONSHIP, THERE HAS TO BE
RESPECT.
AND THAT'S WHAT THE GAME'S
ABOUT.
AT THE END OF THE DAY, YOU WANT
TO BE RESPECTED WHEN YOU COME
OFF THAT FIELD.
WHEN I PLAYED, IN FACT, WE NEVER
HAD A WINNING SEASON WHILE I WAS
THERE.
I WAS TIRED OF LOSING.
SO, THAT'S WHERE MY MIND WAS
WHEN I TOOK THAT SCHOLARSHIP TO
GO TO ALABAMA.
♪
I DON'T KNOW IF I'M EVEN GOOD
ENOUGH TO MAKE THE TEAM.
BUT I'LL GO THERE.
IF I END UP ON THE BENCH, AT
LEAST I KNOW WE'RE WINNING
BECAUSE I KNOW COACH BRYANT IS
GOING TO WIN.
AND IF I'M GOOD ENOUGH TO PLAY
FOR HIM, THEN I KNOW I'M GOOD
ENOUGH TO PLAY FOR ANYBODY.
>> DURING THAT TIME, THERE WERE
CERTAIN POSITIONS THAT THE
BLACKS DIDN'T PLAY, QUARTERBACK,
CENTER ON THE OFFENSE, MIDDLE
LINEBACKER AND SAFETY ON
DEFENSE.
BLACKS DIDN'T PLAY THAT.
ALL OF A SUDDEN YOU'RE WATCHING
THE COACH BRYANT SHOW AND YOU'RE
SEEING HE HAS A BLACK CENTER AND
IT'S SYLVESTER CROOM.
>> THE BEST STORY THAT I CAN
PROBABLY TELL YOU IS THAT WE'RE
GETTING READY TO PLAY KENTUCKY,
AND IT'S ONE OF THE FIRST GAMES
THAT SYLVESTER HAD PLAYED IN,
THEY HAD A BIG NOSE GUARD, HE
WAS A CONCERN THINK.
HE GOES INTO THE GAME AND WHEN
HE CAME OUT, HE HAD A BLOODIED
NOSE.
AND THE TEARS WERE RUNNING DOWN
HIS CHEEK.
AND HE SAID, COACH, WE'RE GOING
LOSE THE GAME.
I CAN'T DO IT.
ABOUT THAT TIME, WE GOT A
TURNAROUND, WE GOT THE BALL
BACK.
HE RAN BACK OUT THERE AND HE HAD
A SMILE FROM ONE EAR TO THE O
OTHER.
HE SAID, I GOT HIM.
I GOT HIM IN MY POCKET.
>> HE LIVED BY EXAMPLE BUT HE
WASN'T AFRAID TO SAY WHAT HE
NEEDED TO SAY.
TO WATCH HIM COME BACK TO THE
HUDDLE, SWEAT DRIPPING, AND GAVE
EVERYTHING THAT HE COULD GIVE ON
THAT PLAY, GETTING READY TO GO
GIVE THAT AMOUNT OF EFFORT ON
THE NEXT PLAY, HE TAUGHT ME HOW
TO BECOME A LEADER, BECAUSE HE
WAS SUCH GREAT LEADER.
♪
>> SPRING PRACTICE FOR THE
CRIMSON TIDE OF ALABAMA.
AND EVERYTHING SEEMS TO BE JUST
LIKE ANY PREVIOUS YEAR.
BUT IT'S NOT.
HEAD COACH BEAR BRYANT SPURS ON
HIS SOUTHEASTERN CONFERENCE
CHAMPS AND AMONG THE PLAYERS,
PASS RECEIVER ANDREW PARNELL,
ONE OF THREE NEGROS ON THE
SQUAD.
ALABAMA GETS READY.
>> I WAS AT THE BARBERSHOP
THE OTHER DAY AND MY BARBER
ASKED ME, WAS COACH BRYANT A
RACIST?
THERE WAS NOT ONE TIME FROM THE
DAY I MET COACH BRYANT THAT I
EVER HEARD A RACIST COMMENT COME
OUT OF HIS MOUTH.
OR DID HE EVER DO ANYTHING TO
MAKE ME THINK THAT HE WAS A
RACIST.
>> THERE WAS NO DISTINCT IN
COLOR.
COACH BRYANT TREATED EVERY
PLAYER THE SAME AND WHEN YOU
WERE IN THE TUSCALOOSA IN THE
STATE OF ALABAMA, WHEN YOU
PLAYED FOR ALABAMA, YOU WERE AN
ALABAMA FOOTBALL PLAYER.
>> I ALWAYS TELL PEOPLE MY DAD
TAUGHT ME HOW TO BE A MAN.
COACH BRYANT FORCED ME TO PUT IT
INTO PRACTICE.
THEIR PHILOSOPHY ABOUT LIFE WAS
TOTALLY IN HARMONY, SO IT WAS A
CONTINUATION OF WHAT I HAD BEEN
HEARING AT HOME.
HE WAS ALWAYS TALKING TO US
ABOUT WHERE OUR LIVES WERE GOING
TO BE 10, 20 YEARS DOWN THE
ROAD.
THE LESSONS WE WERE GOING TO
LEARN FROM THE GAME.
IF YOU CAN DISCIPLINE YOURSELF
TO GET THROUGH THE PRACTICES,
DISCIPLINE YOURSELF TO COME BACK
FROM THIS LOSS, YOU CAN
DISCIPLINE YOURSELF TO KEEP
FIGHTING IN THE FOURTH QUARTER
WHEN YOU'RE BEHIND, THEN THOSE
LESSONS WILL CARRY YOU 10, 20
YEARS FROM NOW, YOU KNOW, WHEN
YOUR WIFE GETS SICK, IF YOU
SHOULD HAVE A CHILD THAT DIES,
IF YOU'RE OUT OF A JOB, YOU'LL
KNOW NOW -- HOW TO FIGHT.
AND HE'S RIGHT.
>> THESE WERE THE TEACHINGS THAT
CROOM ABSORBED ON THE CRIMSON
TIDE AND VALUES THAT HELPED HIM
BECOME A TEAM CAPTAIN AND AN
ALL-AMERICAN HIS SENIOR YEAR, HE
THEN WENT ON TO PLAY A SEASON
FOR THE NFL'S NEW ORLEANS
SAINTS.
BUT QUICKLY RETURNED TO
TUSCALOOSA, WHERE COACH BRYANT
OFFERED HIM A JOB AS AN
ASSISTANT ON HIS STAFF.
CROOM STAYED 11 YEARS, HELPING
THE PROGRAM TO TWO NATIONAL
CHAMPIONSHIPS AND FOUR
SOUTHEASTERN CONFERENCE TITLES.
BUT MOST IMPORTANT, THE SON OF
THE ALABAMA PREACHER WAS
CONTINUING TO SOAK UP THE
TEACHINGS OF HIS LEGENDARY
MENTOR.
>> SYLVESTER FROM THE VERY
BEGINNING WAS A TREMENDOUS COACH
BECAUSE OF HIS DAD AND WHERE
HE WAS FROM AND THE WAY HE
CONDUCTED HIMSELF ON THE
PRACTICE FIELD, HE WAS JUST
TAUGHT THAT EVERYTHING IS GOING
TO BE RIGHT, DON'T GIVE UP.
IF YOU STOOD AND YOU WATCHED IT,
YOU COULD TELL THAT PEOPLE
AROUND HIM HAD RESPECT FOR HIM.
>> SLY WAS VERY SUPPORTIVE OF
THE PLAYERS AND
HE UNDERSTOOD COACH BRYANT AND
HE UNDERSTOOD WHAT NEEDED TO BE
DONE AND WHAT HAD TO BE DONE.
>> I LEARNED A LOT.
BUT HE WAS SO DEMANDING.
YOU LEARN IN A STAFF MEETING,
KEEP YOUR MOUTH SHUT.
DON'T ASK ANYTHING, DON'T SAY
ANYTHING UNLESS HE CALLS YOUR
NAME.
YOU HAD TO BE PERFECT IN
EVERYTHING YOU DID.
HE WAS A GREAT COACH, BUT HE WAS
A GREAT MAN.
AGAIN, HE AND DADDY, THEIR WORD
WAS THEIR BOND.
IF THEY TOLD YOU SOMETHING, IT
WAS GOING TO HAPPEN.
YOU KNEW THAT THEY HAD YOUR BACK
AND THEY WERE ALWAYS GOING TO BE
THERE FOR YOU.
AND THAT'S THE KIND OF MAN I
WANT TO BE.
...and this,
dancing in their heads...
...we have these.
Home Depot gift cards.
Give the gift of doing,
in-store or online.
>>> SYLVESTER CROOM SPENT A
DECADE ON THE SIDELINES AT
ALABAMA BEFORE CONTINUING HIS
COACHING EDUCATION IN THE NFL.
HE WORKED FOR FIVE TEAMS OVER 17
YEARS.
BUILDING A STRONG RESUME AND A
REPUTATION AS ONE OF PRO
FOOTBALL'S MOST POPULAR AND MOST
RESPECTED COACHES.
IN 2003, HE GOT A CALL FROM
TUSCALOOSA.
NO BLACK MAN HAD EVER BEEN A
HEAD COACH IN THE S.E.C.
HIS ALMA MATER WAS CONSIDERING
MAKING CROOM THE FIRST.
>> I WAS EXCITED, BECAUSE THAT'S
TO ME THE PINNACLE OF COLLEGE
FOOTBALL, FIRST OF ALL, A CHANCE
TO BE A HEAD COACH, HEAD COACH
IN THE SOUTHEASTERN CONFERENCE
AND A HEAD COACH AT THE
UNIVERSITY OF ALABAMA.
AND TO BE HONEST WITH YOU, I
FELT LIKE IF ANYBODY IS UP TO
THE CHALLENGE OF GETTING THIS
THING ON THE RIGHT TRACK, IT'S
ME.
>> HE WAS A LEGITIMATE CANDIDATE
IN MY MIND.
I THINK HE UNDERSTOOD ALABAMA
FOOTBALL.
I THINK HE UNDERSTOOD THE ALUMNI
AND HE KNEW THE IMPORTANCE OF
BEING AN ALABAMA FOOTBALL
PLAYER.
IN MY MIND, THERE WAS NO
QUESTION BASED ON WHAT HE HAD
GONE THROUGH IN HIS LIFE, HE WAS
READY TO TAKE THAT JOB.
>> WE WERE VERY EXCITED ABOUT
THE OPPORTUNITY.
I REMEMBER COACH BRYANT WHEN HE
CAME BACK, HE SAID, WHEN MAMA
CALLS, YOU HAVE TO COME AND
ANSWER.
AS A RESULT, WE SAW MAMA CALLING
AND I WAS EXCITED TO HAVE THE
OPPORTUNITY FOR MY BROTHER TO
COME BACK HOME.
>> LADIES AND GENTLEMEN, OUR
ALABAMA HEAD FOOTBALL COACH,
MIKE SHULA.
>> I WAS LED TO BELIEVE THAT THE
JOB WAS MINE AT ONE POINT.
AND IT CHANGED.
WITHIN THE ADMINISTRATION, I
DON'T THINK IT WAS A PROBLEM.
I KNEW IT WASN'T A PROBLEM WITH
THE FORMER PLAYERS.
I KNEW IT WAS NOT A PROBLEM WITH
THE ALABAMA FAN BASE EITHER.
BUT SOMEWHERE ALONG THE CHAIN OF
COMMAND, SOMEBODY SAID NO.
>> IT'S PLAIN AND SIMPLE.
ALABAMA THAT POINT, WAS NOT
READY TO HIRE BLACK HEAD
FOOTBALL COACH.
THAT'S NOT TO POINT A FINGER AT
ALABAMA.
THERE WERE A LOT OF SCHOOLS IN
THE S.E.C. THAT JUST COULDN'T OR
WOULDN'T HIRE A BLACK HEAD
FOOTBALL COACH.
>> I FELT THAT WE NEEDED A
FORMER PLAYER, YOU KNOW, TO HELP
US THROUGH A TOUGH TIME.
AND IN THE END, YOU KNOW, WE
FELT THAT SHULA'S NAME WOULD BE
A RECRUITING STRENGTH FOR US.
HE WAS A GREAT PLAYER HERE.
GREAT QUARTERBACK.
COACHED IN THE PROS.
A LOT TO SELL.
>> I THINK IT WAS A VERY
REGRETTABLE MOMENT IN ALABAMA
HISTORY AND WHAT PEOPLE TOLD ME
WAS, SLY DIDN'T INTERVIEW WELL.
OKAY, ARE YOU HIRING A
CONTESTANT FOR "AMERICAN IDOL"
OR ARE YOU HIRING A GOOD
FOOTBALL COACH?
AND MIKE SHULA HAD THE
ADVANTAGES.
THERE WAS A PERFECT WIFE.
THEY LOOKS LIKE THE COUPLE ON
THE TOP OF A WEDDING CAKE.
SYLVESTER CROOM WAS MORE
QUALIFIED THAN MIKE SHULA AND
THAT'S THE ONLY MEASURE YOU HAVE
TO LOOK AT.
>> WE GREW UP IN THE SOUTH.
I GREW UP IN THIS ALL THE TIME
WHEN MAYBE YOU WERE THE BEST
CANDIDATE, OR THE BEST PERSON
FOR THE JOB, AND YOU DON'T GET
THE JOB, BUT DON'T MEAN YOU
QUIT, YOU HAVE TO KEEP STRIVING,
YOU HAVE TO KEEP GOING, THAT'S
WHAT MADE US SO GREAT SO FAR.
>> THESE ARE THE KIND OF THINGS
THAT COACH BRYANT TALKED ABOUT.
HOW ARE YOU GOING TO GET UP?
HOW DO YOU MOVE FORWARD?
YOU GET OFF THE GROUND, DUST
YOURSELF OFF AND YOU GO BACK TO
WORK.
DOING THE BEST JOB AT WHATEVER N
IT IS YOU'RE DOING.
BEING THE BEST YOU CAN BE.
>> IT WAS A PHILOSOPHY THAT
HAD EARNED HIM THE INTERVIEW AT
ALABAMA.
AS THE 2003 SEASON WOUND DOWN,
ANOTHER S.E.C. PROGRAM IN NEED
CAME CALLING.
75 MILES WEST OF TUSCALOOSA,
MISSISSIPPI STATE HEAD COACH
JACKIE SHERRILL WAS RETIRING,
AND ATHLETIC DIRECTOR LARRY
TEMPLETON WAS LEADING A SEARCH
FOR A REPLACEMENT.
BUT THE PROGRAM WAS FACING
PENALTIES FROM THE NCAA AND
ALREADY SUFFERING WITH ONE OF
THE CONFERENCE'S WEAKEST
ROSTERS.
>> THERE WAS NO QUESTION ABOUT
HIS INTEGRITY, HIS LOYALTY.
BUT HE CAME TO THAT INTERVIEW TO
TELL US HE WAS NOT GOING TO
ACCEPT THE JOB.
>> FIRST OF ALL, I DON'T WANT TO
BE THE TOKEN BLACK COACH.
THE SECOND THING IS THAT, DO YOU
REALIZE HOW BAD THE PROGRAM IS
RIGHT NOW?
I DON'T WANT TO WIN ONE OR TWO
YEARS.
I WANT TO BUILD A PROGRAM THAT
10 OR 20 YEARS DOWN THE ROAD IS
STILL A CHAMPIONSHIP PROGRAM.
IN ORDER FOR ME TO DO THAT, I
SAID, I'VE GOT TO BUILD IT MY
WAY.
AND THAT MEANS, IF I HAVE TO
BLOW IT UP AND START ALL OVER
AGAIN THAT'S WHAT I'M GOING TO
DO.
>> PRESIDENT LEE DID AN
UNBELIEVABLE JOB SETTING THE
TABLE AND SYLVESTER WASN'T
BUYING INTO IT AT ALL.SAID, I S
WOULD YOUR DADDY WANT YOU TO DO?
HE LOOKED UP AT ME AND SAID,
YOU'RE NOT PLAYING FAIR.
>> I CALLED A GOOD FRIEND OF
MINE WHO IS NOW DECEASED, NAMED
MILT JACKSON.
I SAID I'M NOT GOING TO TAKE
THAT STATE JOB AND THERE WAS A
PAUSE ON THE OTHER END OF THE
LINE, HE SAID, BUDDY, YOU HAVE
TO TAKE THE JOB.
HE SAID, FOR WHATEVER REASON,
YOU HAVE BEEN CHOSEN.
YOU'RE THE ONE AND YOU HAVE TO
GO.
>> COACH SYLVESTER CROOM, I KNOW
THAT I SPEAK FOR THE ENTIRE
BULLDOG FAMILY WHEN I SAY
WELCOME TO THE PEOPLE'S
UNIVERSITY AND TO THE GREAT
STATE OF MISSISSIPPI.
WE ARE HONORED BY YOUR TRUST IN
US AND THE POTENTIAL THAT YOU
BRING TO THIS UNIVERSITY, TO
THIS FOOTBALL PROGRAM, AND TO
THIS STATE, WELCOME TO THE
CROOM ERA OF BULLDOG FOOTBALL.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> I'M LOOKING AT A COACH, I'M
NOT SEEING A BLACK COACH.
I'M SEEING THE COACH OF
MISSISSIPPI STATE, WHO HAPPENS
TO BE MY BROTHER.
I KNEW THE LESSONS HE HAD BEEN
TAUGHT BY MY MOM AND DAD.
TAUGHT BY COACH BRYANT.
AND I KNEW THE THINGS THAT HE
HAD BEEN THROUGH HIMSELF WOULD
HELP HIM TO BE GREAT FIT FOR
MISSISSIPPI STATE.
>> IT WAS A STORY NOT ABOUT
SPORT BUT IT WAS A STORY ABOUT
US, IT WAS A STORY ABOUT
SOCIETY, IT WAS A STORY ABOUT
THE SOUTH.
I DON'T BELIEVE THERE WILL BE A
MORE PIVOTAL EVENT IN MY TEN
YO URE
NO MATTER HOW LONG I STAY HERE.
>> THE REASON A LOT OF YOU ARE
HERE IS BECAUSE OF ME.
BECAUSE OF MY CULTURAL HERITAGE,
WHICH I'M PROUD OF.
BUT AT THE SAME TIME, IT'S NOT
ABOUT ME.
IT'S ABOUT THESE YOUNG MEN
STANDING OVER HERE TO MY RIGHT
AND THAT'S WHY I'M HERE.
>> WITH ALL OF THOSE BRIGHT
LIGHTS AND THE SUFFOCATING
PRESSURE OF THE MOMENT, WHAT DID
S
SYLVESTER CROOM DO?
HE MADE THE MOST OF IT.
HE TOOK THE MANTLE FROM PAUL
BRYANT AT THAT MOMENT.
AND FOR A SINGULAR MOMENT STOOD
ABOVE ALMOST ANYBODY ELSE IN THE
GAME.
>> THE OTHER THING I WANT TO
MAKE SURE EVERYBODY UNDERSTANDS,
I AM THE FIRST AFRICAN-AMERICAN
COACH IN THE S.E.C.
BUT THERE AIN'T ONE COLOR THAT
MATTERS HERE, AND THAT COLOR IS
MAROON.
>> IT WAS A STRONG FIRST
IMPRESSION, BUT THE CULMINATION
OF THE PATH HE HAD BEEN ON FROW.
AND IS CIVIL RIGHTS MOVEMENT WAS
ADVANCING ALL AROUND HIM.
SO MANY YEARS LATER, SYLVESTER
CROOM SURVEYED HIS NEW
SURROUNDING, HIS NEW UNIVERSITY,
HIS NEW CHALLENGE, HE SPENT HIS
LIFE PREPARING FOR THIS MOMENT.
NOW, IN AMERICA'S DEEP SOUTH, IT
WAS TIME TO BUILD A FOOTBALL
PROGRAM IN HIS IMAGE.
[ Woman ]
♪ WHAT I WANT THIS SEASON
♪ IF YOU'D LIKE
TO TRY AND GUESS ♪
IT IS SOMETHING VERY SPECIAL ♪
♪ I WOULD READILY CONFESS
[ dogs barking ]
♪ 'CAUSE ALL I WANT
THIS SEASON ♪
♪ IS SOMETHING FROM YOUR HEART
♪A DA DA, LDA DA
[ Male Annouer THINKING
OFOF OTHERS THIS HOLIDAY SEAS,
TRAVELERS.
♪
>>> WHERE ARE WE AT TODAY,
COACH, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
>> WE'RE IN JACKSON,
MISSISSIPPI.
WE'RE GOING TO THE JACKSON
SPORTS CLUB.
WE'RE AT THE SPOTS HALL OF FAME
THE WHERE WE'RE HAVING THE
MEETING TONIGHT.
ANOTHER STOP ON THE JOURNE
COACH BRYANT WOULD ALWAYS
SAY, IF THE OTHER TEAM WON THE
NEXT WEEK, WE DIDN'T HIT THEM
HARD ENOUGH.
WHAT I WANT FOR OUR PROGRAM IS
PRETTY SIMPLE -- I WANT A TOTAL
COMMITMENT TO EXCELLENCE.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> SYLVESTER IS ONE OF THOSE
GUYS WHO WILL TELL YOU EXACTLY
HOW HE FEELS.
THERE WAS NOTHING PHONY ABOUT
IT.
HE KNEW GOING IN THERE WHAT A
JOB HE FACED.
>> WE'RE TRYING TO CREATE A TEAM
OF WINNERS.
WINNERS ON THE FIELD.
WINNERS IN THE CLASSROOM, BUT
MORE IMPORTANTLY, WINNERS IN
LIFE.
>> THERE WAS A VERY DIVIDED
YOU HAD PART OF THE COMMUNITY,
PART OF THE ALUMNI, PART OF THE
BOOSTERS THAT WERE EXCITED ABOUT
THE CHANGE, THAT WELCOMED THE
CHANGE, THAT KNEW IT WAS THE
DIRECTION THAT NEEDED TO BE
TAKEN.
AND QUITE FRANKLY, YOU HAD A
GROUP THAT WERE VERY COMFORTABLE
IN THE OLD REGIME, VERY
COMFORTABLE IN THE OLD WAY OF
DOING THINGS.
>> THE FIRST MEETING I HAD WITH
THE PLAYERS, I TOLD THEM, IF ANY
OF YOU IN HERE ARE RECEIVING
ANYTHING ABOVE YOUR SCHOLARSHIP,
END IT RIGHT NOW.
I SAID, BECAUSE IF I FIND OUT
ABOUT IT, YOU WILL BE OFF
SCHOLARSHIP.
WE'RE GOING TO GO ABSOLUTELY AND
STRICTLY BY THE RULES.
>> WE HAD GUYS ON OUR TEAM THAT
HAD BEEN CONVICTED OF PASSING
COUNTERFEIT MONEY.
WE HAD GUYS THAT HAD SMALL DRUG
CHARGES.
WE HAD GUYS THAT WERE ARRESTED,
CHARGED AND CONVICTED OF
FELONIES.
IN OUR FIRST TWO YEARS THERE, 35
PLAYERS LEFT THE PROGRAM.
IT WOULD HAVE BEEN EASY FOR
COACH CROOM LET THOSE PLAYERS
STAY AND WIN A FEW MORE GAMES
BUT HE KNEW THE HARD LINE THAT
HAD TO BE TAKEN.
>> LADIES AND GENTLEMEN, AT THIS
TIME, PLEASE WELCOME IN THE
MAROON AND WHITE, OUR HEAD
COACH, SYLVESTER CROOM!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> WINNING WAS VERY IMPORTANT TO
HIM.
BUT IT WASN'T GOING TO CHANGE
HIS ETHICS OR CHANGE WHAT WAS
RIGHT, WHAT HE THOUGHT WAS
RIGHT, TO GIVE US A BETTER
CHANCE TO WIN.
>> GET THE FIRST DOWN.
>> OKAY.
>> IT WAS A NICE RUN, BUT
GET THAT FIRST DOWN FOR US.
>> HE WAS LIKE A LIGHTHOUSE.
HE NEVER CHANGED.
THIS IS HOW WE DO IT.
IF YOU STAY HERE, YOU'LL BE A
CHAMPION.
>> ONE, TWO, THREE --
>> HE WANTED TO MAKE SURE THAT
THE YOUNG MEN LEFT WITH A DEGREE
AND THAT WAS HIS NUMBER ONE GOAL
AND THAT'S DEFINITELY WHERE HE
AND I CLICKED.
IT WASN'T NECESSARILY ALL ABOUT
FOOTBALL AND WHAT THEY DID.
HERE AT MISSISSIPPI STATE.
BUT IT WAS GOING TO BE WHAT
THEY'RE GOING TO DO FOR THE REST
OF THEIR LIVES.
>> HEY, WAIT A MINUTE, YOU GOT
TO EXPLAIN TO ME ABOUT THIS
AMERICAN HISTORY NOW.
I AIN'T GETTING THAT NUMBER.
YOU HAVE BEEN ON THE DEAN'S LIST
EVER SINCE YOU HAVE BEEN HERE
AND YOU CAN'T PASS AMERICAN
HISTORY?
I COULD HAVE HELPED YOU WITH
THAT!
WHEN I WENT INTO A PLAYER'S HOME
AND TOLD MOM AND DAD THAT I WAS
GOING TO TREAT THEIR SON LIKE HE
WAS MINE, THAT WAS THE TRUTH.
IF YOU SEND YOUR BOY TO ME, IF
YOU SEND HIM TO OUR PROGRAM,
FOUR YEARS FROM NOW, YOU'LL GET
A GROWN MAN BACK.
HE'LL BE PREPARED TO PROVIDE FOR
HIMSELF AND HIS FAMILY, HE WILL
HAVE HIS DEGREE, BECAUSE IF HE
COMES HERE, I WILL NOT PLAY HIM
IF HE WON'ASS.
I'M NOT GOING TO EXPLOIT HIS
ATHLETIC TALENTS AND THEN HE
LEAVES HERE WITH NOTHING.
THAT WAS A PROMISE I MADE TO
EVERY ONE OF OUR PARENTS.
♪
>> IN SEPTEMBER OF 2004, CROOM'S
FIRST SEASON, MISSISSIPPI STATE
TRAVELED TO BATON ROUGE TO FACE
ONE OF THE S.E.C.'S TOP
COLLEGES, LSU.
FROM THE OPENING KICKOFF, THE
STORYLINE WAS SET.
THE TIGERS WERE FASTER,
STRONGER, AND BETTER THAN
CROOM'S BULLDOGS.
THE CONFERENCE RIVALS WERE IN
DIFFERENT STRATOSPHERES.
>> WE WERE NOT AN S.E.C.-QUALITY
FOOTBALL TEAM.
♪
>> DOWN HE GOES.
INTERCEPTED!
>> IT WAS UNBELIEVABLE.
I THINK IT WAS 32 -- 33-0 AT THE
HALF.
AND WE COME BACK OUT.
ABOUT THE MIDDLE OF THE THIRD
QUARTER.
ONE OF OUR SPECIAL TEAMS COACHES
SAY, THESE ARE NOT THEIR
STARTERS ARE THEY?
BEAUTIFUL LOOKING PLAYERS OUT
THERE.
HE SAID, NO, COACH, THOSE ARE
HIS FRESHMEN.
YOU KNOW WHAT I LEARNED?
IT TAKES TIME TO CHANGE CULTURE.
IT TAKES TIME TO CHANGE AN
ATTITUDE.
IT TAKES TIME TO BUILD ANYTHING
THAT'S WORTHWHILE HAVING AND YOU
CAN'T SPEED IT UP.
>> BIG IN THIS DAY AND AGE IS
THE KIND OF CHARACTER AND
ATTITUDE YOU HAVE IN THE PLAYERS
THAT ARE THERE.
THE KIND OF PEOPLE THEY ARE.
AND TO HAVE SOME OF THOSE
INGREDIENTS IN PLACE, SOMETIMES
YOU CAN TURN THINGS AROUND A OWU
DO WHAT SYLVESTER TRIED TO DO AT
MISSISSIPPI STATE, I THINK THAT
TAKES TIME, BECAUSE HE HAD TO
REBUILD THE WHOLE THING FROM THE
FOUNDATION.
>> WHEN YOU THINK YOU CAN'T, YOU
CAN.
AND IT'S JUST THE MENTAL
TOUGHNESS THAT HE HAD AND THE
MENTAL TOUGHNESS THAT HIS
FOOTBALL TEAM HAD.
A LOT OF FOOTBALL TEAMS THAT GO
3-8, 4-7, THEY QUIT.
WE MAY HAVE GONE 3-8, 4-7, BUT
WE NEVER QUIT, EVER.
>> THAT'S THE WAY YOU OUGHT TO
DO IT.
>> BE PROUD OF YOURSELVES.
>> WE TALKED ABOUT WHAT WE
WANTED OUR IDENTITY TO BE.
WE WANTED TO BE A DISCIPLINED
FOOTBALL TEAM.
WE WANT TO OUTWORK EVERYBODY
ELSE, OUTHUSTLE EVERYBODY ELSE.
WE WERE GOING TO OUTHIT
EVERYBODY ELSE.
BUT I ALSO TOLD THAT THEY WERE A
PART OF BUILDING SOMETHING
SPECIAL.YOU GUYS ARE LAYING
THE FOUNDATION.
I SAID, YOU WON'T BE HERE WHEN
WE REAP THE REWARDS.
BUT I'LLET
YOU. NEVER LET THEM FORGET
YOU.
AND THEY BELIEVED.
AND THAT'S WHAT KEPT THEM GOING.
THEY WERE PLAYING FOR SOMETHING
BIGGER THAN THEMSELVES.
I LOVE THOSE KIDS.
THEY TRUSTED ME.
can see, GEICOs
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a l latte will y,
please?
>>> MISSISSIPPI STATE WON JUST
THREE GAMES EACH OF SYLVESTER
CROOM'S FIRST TWO SEASONS, STILL
HANDICAPPED BY THE NCAA
PUNISHMENTS THAT PRECEDED HIS
ARRIVAL THERE.
IN LATE 2006, IT DIDN'T LOOK
MUCH BETTER AND THE BULLDOGS
WERE STILL WINLESS IN SECTION
PLAY WHEN THEY RETURNED TO
TUSCALOOSA.
IT WAS A RETURN TO CROOM'S ROOTS
AND A BITTER REMINDER OF A DREAM
UNFULFILLED.
>> OUR PLAYERS WANTED TO DO IT
FOR HIM.
YOU COULD FEEL THAT NO MATTER
WHO WE WERE PLAYING, BUT IN '06,
WE WEREN'T A VERY GOOD FOOTBALL
TEAM.
>> I THINK IT WAS A LOT OF
PERSON IN THAT MOMENT, WE HAD IT
IN THE BACK OF OUR MINDS THAT IS
A REAL IMPORTANT GAME FOR HIM
AND WE JUST WANTED TO GO OUT
THERE AND GIVE HIM THE BEST
OPPORTUNITY.
GO OUT THERE AND WIN.
>> I KNEW THAT WE COULDN'T MAKE
MISTAKES.
BUT THEY MADE A MISTAKE IN THE
BALL GAME.
THEY TOOK THE BALL DROVE IT DOWN
THE FIELD AND DECIDED TO GO FOR
A TOUCHDOWN INSTEAD OF A FIELD
GOAL.
THEY WERE GOING TO PUT THE NAIL
IN OUR COFFIN AND FINISH THE
BALL GAME RIGHT THERE.
>> TWO SECONDS TO GO IN THE
HALF.
HE PUMPS.
HIT AT THE 1 YARD LINE.
DID HE GET INTO THE END ZONE?
NO SIGNAL YET!
>> OH, WOW, WHAT A HIT!
>> THE DEFENSE STOPS ALABAMA ON
THE FINAL PLAY OF THE HALF.
BIG FINISH BY SYLVESTER CROOM
AND HIS DEFENSE WITH A STAND
THAT GIVES THEM PLENTY OF
MOMENTUM HEADING INTO THE LOCKER
ROOM AT HALFTIME.
>> WHEN OUR GUYS WERE ABLE TO
RISE UP AND STOP THEM, I KNEW
THEN THAT THEY WERE GOING TO
HAVE TO STEAL THE GAME FROM US
WHEN WE WENT BACK OUT IN THE
SECOND HALF.
OUR KIDS IN THE LOCKER ROOM, I
COULD SEE IT IN THEIR EYES.
>> WHAT A HUGE VICTORY FOR THE
BULLDOGS, FIRST TIME THEY HAVE
BEEN ABLE TO COME IN HERE AND
WIN A GAME IN TUSCALOOSA SINCE
1997.
>> IT WAS REALLY A MEASURING
STICK BETWEEN COACH CROOM AND
COACH SHULA.
AND THAT'S WHY THAT DAY IN 2006
WAS SO SPECIAL.
BECAUSE, THE REALIZATION THAT
THEIR FAVORITE SON LOST JUST
LIKE CROOM, IT TOOK THAT TO GET
RID OF MIKE SHULA.
>> LISTEN UP, GUYS.
SHOW A LOT OF CLASS NOW.
REMEMBER, YOU BEAT A HELL OF A
PROGRAM.
A HELL OF A LOT OF TRADITION
OVER THERE.
BUT THE THINGS THAT WE TALK
ABOUT, THAT THEY TALK ABOUT,
THAT COACH BRYANT TAUGHT ME AND
TAUGHT THEM, IS THAT, HEART,
FIGHT, TEAMWORK, SACRIFICE.
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE GOING TO MAKE
MISSISSIPPI STATE.
THAT'S WHAT'S GOING TO TAKE US
TO THE NATIONAL CHAMPIONSHIP.
IT'S GOING TO COME, WE GOT TO
KEEP DOING WHAT WE'RE DOING AND
KEEP BELIEVING.
I'M SO PROUD OF YOU, YOU
SENIORS, FOR HANGING IN THERE,
YOU STOOD THE TEST.
MEN, YOU'RE GAME WINNERS.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> FOR THE BETTER PART OF THREE
SEASONS, THE MAN IN THE HUDDLE
HAD BEEN BUILDING SOMETHING IN
THIS LOCKER ROOM.
LIKE ANY PROGRESS, IT WASN'T
ALWAYS VISIBLE UNTIL SUDDENLY
THAT DAY IN TUSCALOOSA.
THE WIN IN ALABAMA WAS THE ONLY
VICTORY THAT SEASON.
BUT THE SIGNIFICANCE WAS
UNDENIABLE.
SUPPORTERS WERE WEARY WAITING
FOR CROOM'S TEAM TO TAKE THE
NEXT STEP FORWARD.
BUT NOW, THEIR BIGGEST MOMENT IN
YEARS PLANTED A SEED FOR THE
MOMENT TO COME.
>> GOING INTO 2007, WE BELIEVED
THAT WE COULD WIN.
AGAIN, WE WEREN'T AN OVERLY
TALENTED TEAM.
BUT THE '07 SEASON WAS REALLY
WHEN WE STARTED GET THE TOP
RECRUITS AT MISSISSIPPI.
>> THERE WAS A SENSE OF URGENCY
BECAUSE WE HAD BEEN THERE THREE
YEARS.
OUR STAFF HAD BEEN TOGETHER
FOR QUITE SOME TIME AND IT CAME
TOGETHER IN A WAY THAT I DON'T
THINK ANYONE EVER EXPECTED.
>> YOU COULD SEE SOME SUCCESS
FOR ALL THE HARD WORK, ALL THE
SACRIFICE, ALL THE TOUGH
DECISIONS THAT HE HAD MADE.
IT WAS KIND OF A JOY TO BE
AROUND AND KIND OF STICK YOUR
CHEST OUT.
WE ARE MISSISSIPPI STATE.
>> BY NOVEMBER THE BULLDOGS WERE
IN CONTENTION FOR A BOWL BERTH
FOR THE FIRST TIME SINCE 2000,
THEY WERE PLAYING THE STYLE THAT
THEIR COACH PREACHED AND WINNING
JUST AS HE HAD PROMISED.
AND WHEN ALABAMA AND THEIR NEW
COACH, NICK SABAN, CAME INTO
TOWN FOR A CRUCIAL SHOWDOWN,
THEY WERE FACING A WHOLE
DIFFERENT MSU.
>> GREAT DAY, MEN.
GREAT DAY.
THINK ABOUT ALL OF THE THINGS
THAT WE HAVE BEEN THROUGH, YOU
SENIORS, ALL THAT WE HAVE BEEN
THROUGH TOGETHER.
WE FACED MORE IN PERSON THAT
MOST FOOTBALL TEAMS SHOULD EVER
HAVE TO DEAL WITH.
TODAY, WE GO INTO THE GAME WITH
A RARE OPPORTUNITY.
JUST BY PLAYING THE GAME TO THE
BEST OF YOUR ABILITY, YOU CAN
HAVE AN IMPACT ON A LOT OF
PEOPLE'S LIVES JUST BY THE WAY
YOU PLAY YOUR GAME.
IF YOU PLAY IT AS GOOD AS YOU
PLAY, IN THREE HOURS, WE'LL
CHANGE THE WAY PEOPLE LOOK AT
THIS UNIVERSITY FOR A LONG TIME.
WE'LL CHANGE THE WAY PEOPLE LOOK
AT STARKVILLE AND CHANGE THE WAY
PEOPLE LOOK AT OUR STATE IN THE
NEXT THREE HOURS.
JUST BY PLAYING THE GAME.
PLAY WITH PRIDE.
PLAY WITH PASSION.
THIS IS OUR BIG DAY.
THIS IS OUR BIG GAME.
GO OUT THERE.
PLAY FOR TODAY!
GET READY TO ROLL!
>> WHAT TIME IS IT?
>> All: GAME TIME!
>> THE DOG'S IN THE HOUSE!
♪
>> BOOTLEG PRESSURE, BY WILSON.
IT'S PICKED OFF.
HE'S GOING TO TAKE IT TO THE
HOUSE.
END ZONE TO END ZONE, TOUCHDOWN
BULLDOGS!
AND JUST LIKE THAT, THE MOMENTUM
OF THIS ENTIRE FOOTBALL GAME HAS
CHANGED.
♪
>> MISSISSIPPI STATE --
LOOKING TO HIM.
ON THE OUTSIDE.
TOUCHDOWN!
♪
>> IT'S OVER!
A BIG WIN AT HOME, THE
CELEBRATION IS ON IN STARKVILLE,
MISSISSIPPI STATE FIGHTS OFF
ALABAMA, 17-12.
>> WHAT A GREAT WIN FOR
SYLVESTER CROOM!
HIS TEAM IS A MIRROR IMAGE OF
WHO HE IS.
♪
>> I THOUGHT HE DID A PHENOMENAL
JOB AT MISSISSIPPI STATE.
NOT ONLY IMPROVING THE TALENT
LEVEL THEY HAD THERE, THE
DISCIPLINE THEY HAD, THE WAY
THEY COMPETED ON THE FIELD, I
HAVE KNOWN SYLVESTER FOR A LONG
TIME.
I THINK HE'S ONE OF THE BEST
COACHES OUT THERE, ONE OF THE
FINEST MEN YOU'RE EVER GOING TO
FIND AND CERTAINLY A GUY THAT
HAS HAD A REAL POSITIVE IMPACT
ON A LOT OF YOUNG PEOPLE.
>> TWO WEEKS LATER, THE
BULLDOGS' LAST GAME OF THE
REGULAR SEASON WAS AGAINST
BITTER IN-STATE RIVAL OLE MISS
IN A GAME THEY CALLED THE EGG
BOWL.
MSU WAS FAVORED.
BUT AT THE START OF THE FOURTH
QUARTER, THEY FOUND HETHEMSELVE
TRAILING BY TWO TOUCHDOWNS.
>> I CAN REMEMBER THAT FOOTBALL
GAME.
I SAID TO MYSELF, THE CHARACTER
OF THIS FOOTBALL TEAM, WHICH IS
THE IS SPITTING IMAGE OF THIS
CHARACTER OF THE FOOTBALL COACH.
>> MORE THAN ANYTHING IT'S JUST
HANGING TOGETHER AS A TEAM AND
FIGHTING TO OVERCOME THE ODDS.
MOST OF THE PLAYERS COME FROM
BACKGROUNDS.
THEIR FAMILIES HAD TO FIGHT LIKE
THAT.
SO, YEAH, THAT'S WHO WE WERE.
WE WERE FIGHTERS.
>> SYLVESTER CROOM IS GOING TO
TAKE A SHOT RIGHT HERE.
ON SECOND DOWN.
THEY'LL ATTEMPT A FIELD GOAL
FROM 48 YARDS.
FOR THE WIN.
IT'S ON THE WAY!
IT'S GOOD!
♪
>> FOUR YEARS HAD PASSED SINCE
CROOM HAD BEC THE S.E.C.'S
FIRST BLACK HEAD COACH.
NOW HE HAD BEEN VOTED BY HIS
PEERS THE CONFERENCE'S COACH OF
THE YEAR.
AND IN THE LIBERTY BOWL, THE
BULLDOGS' VICTORY GAVE THEM A
WINNING SEASON FOR THE FIRST
TIME IN SEVEN YEARS.
COACH CROOM HAD BUILT A FOOTBALL
PROGRAM FROM THE GROUND UP.
AND HE HAD DONE EVERYTHING HE
COULD TO BUILD THE CHARACTER OF
HIS PLAYERS ALONG THE WAY.
>> AFTER WE WON THE LIBERTY
BOWL, I WENT TO HIM TO GIVE HIM
THE REPORT ON OUR SEMESTER
GRADES.
AND GIVE HIM THE NEWS THAT THE
TEAM HAS JUST ACHIEVED THE
HIGHEST GPA IN TEAM HISTORY.
COMING OFF A BIG WIN LIKE WE DID
IN A BIG SEASON HE WAS JUST
ELATED BECAUSE EVERYTHING HAD
JUST COME TOGETHER FOR HIM.  '0,
I FELT VERY GOOD ABOUT WHERE OUR
PROGRAM WAS.
AND I TOLD THE TEAM, I SAID,
GUYS, IF WE JUST STAY FOCUSED,
WE'LL HAVE A CHANCE TO COMPETE
FOR THE CONFERENCE TITLE THIS
YEAR.
I LEARNED SOMETHING, IN THIS
BUSINESS, YOU GOT TO TAKE IT ONE
DAY AT A TIME.
DON'T PLAN TOO FAR DOWN THE
ROAD.
TAKE IT ONE DAY AT A TIME.
[ Woman ]
♪ WHAT I WANT THIS SEASON
♪ IF YOU'D LIKE
TO TRY AND GUESS ♪
♪ IT IS SOMETHING VERY SPECIAL
♪ I WOULD READILY CONFESS
[ dogs barking ]
♪CAUSE ALL I WANT
THIS SEASON ♪
♪ IS SOMETHINING FROM YOUR HEAR
♪ LA DA DA, LA DA DA
[ Male Announcer ] THINKING
OF OTHERS THIS HOLIDAY SEASON,
TRAVELERERS.
For thos...this...ions of doing
this...
...and this,
dancing in their heads...
...we ha these.
Home Depot gift cards.
Give the gift of doing,
in-store or online.
>>> IT WAS 2008, THE LAST NIGHT
OF SPRING PRACTICE IN
STARKVILLE, MISSISSIPPI,
SYLVESTER CROOM HAD GONE HOME TO
WORK ON HIS SCHEDULE FOR THE
FALL, WHEN A STRONG NEW CLASS OF
RECRUITS WOULD BE JOINING THE
TEAM.
THEN TAME THE F CALL FROM
THE UNIVERSITY PRESIDENT'S
OFFICE.
A FEW MILES AWAY, SHOTS HAD BEEN
FIRED, PLAYERS WERE INVOLVED,
ARRESTS WERE MADE, AND THE
PUNISHMENTS WERE DECISIVE.
>> AS SOON AS THAT HAPPENED,
THEY'RE GONE AND THEY WERE ALL
TOP-NOTCH PLAYERS, THERE WERE
ACTUALLY FIVE OF THEM INVOLVED
AND TWO OF THEM WERE OUR BEST
DEFENSIVE PLAYERS.
AND FROM THEN ON, THE REST OF
THE YEAR WAS A NIGHTMARE.
WE LOST OUR OFFENSIVE
COORDINATOR, WHO WAS A VERY,
VERY VALUABLE PART OF OUR
PROGRAM.
CHANEY BREAKS HIS LEG.
SO AS WE GET INTO THE SEASON
NOW, WE'RE NOT A CONFERENCE
FOOTBALL TEAM.
IT'S AS IF WE EVERYTHING WE
LEARNED AND HAD DONE FROM THE
FIRST YEAR WE GOT THERE, UNTIL
2007, IT ALL DISAPPEARED.
WHAT I WAS MOST DISAPPOINTED IN
WAS THAT -- I DIDN'T HAVE ANY
SUPPORT.
WITHIN THE DEPARTMENT.
ESPECIALLY WHEN THEY KNEW WHAT
HAPPENED DURING THE COURSE OF
THE SEASON.
>> IT WAS A NEW ATHLETIC
DIRECTOR THERE.
LARRY TEMPLETON WAS GONE.
HE WAS THE GUY WHO HIRED
SYLVESTER.
THEY HAD SOME EMBARRASSING
DEFEATS.
YOU GO BACK TO OLE MISS DEBACLE,
TO LOSE LIKE THAT, YOUR BITTER
STATE RIVAL, WHAT YOU DID A YEAR
AGO, TWO YEARS AGO.
NO FAN HAS A MEMORY THAT LONG.
>> AS YOU EVALUATE YOUR FOOTBALL
PROGRAM LIKE YOU EVALUATE YOUR
BASEBALL PROGRAM OR SOFTBALL
PROGRAM, YOU HAVE TO SAY, ARE WE
HEADED IN THE RIGHT DIRECTION
LONG TERM?
WE STRUGGLED FROM A HISTORICAL
STANDPOINT IN THE LAST FIVE
YEARS OFFENSIVELY.
AND SO, BASED OFF EVALUATING
THOSE THINGS AND OUR
CONVERSATIONS WITH COACH CROOM,
HE OFFERED HIS RESIGNATION AND
WE WENT OUT AND HIRED DAN MULLEN
AS OUR NEXT HEAD FOOTBALL COACH.
>> YOU HAVE TO WIN AND YOU HAVE
TO BE SUCCESSFUL ON A CONSISTENT
BASIS AND YOU HAVE TO BEAT YOUR
RIVAL.
>> WHO KNOWS HOW THIS STORY
WOULD HAVE ENDED IF SYLVESTER
CROOM CUT CORNERS LIKE SO MANY
OTHER COACHES?
IF HE TOOK PLAYERS THAT HE
DIDN'T BELIEVE IN?
BUT THAT WASN'T WHO HE WAS.
BUT THINK IN THE END, HE MAY
HAVE LOST THE JOB AT MISSISSIPPI
STATE BECAUSE OF WHAT HE STOOD
FOR.
>> WHEN I WAS ASKED TO LEAVE,
ONE OF THE CONDITIONS WAS, LET
ME TALK TO THE TEAM ONE MORE
TIME.
AND IN THAT MEETING I TOLD THEM,
I WAS GOING TO MAKE SURE THAT
THEY CONTINUED TO WORK HARD AND
WIN AN S.E.C. CHAMPIONSHIP AND
FINISH WHAT WE HAD STARTED.
MY LAST STATEMENT TO THEM WAS,
MAKE SURE YOU ALWAYS UNDERSTAND
THAT I LOVE YOU.
AND YOU KNOW I DIDN'T QUIT ON
YOU.
WHEN I TOOK THE JOB, I INTENDED
FOR THAT TO BE MY LAST COACHING
JOB.
AND I MADE IT CLEAR TO MY
PLAYERS THAT I DIDN'T QUIT.
I WAS ASKED TO RESIGNED.
>> HE HAD COME TO MISSISSIPPI
STATE A MAN WHO KNEW VERY WELL
THAT LIFE ISN'T ALWAYS FAIR AND
PROGRESS CAN'T EVER BE PERFECT.
AS THE SOUTHEASTERN CONFERENCE'S
FIRST BLACK FOOTBALL COACH, THE
WINS AND LOSSES WERE ALWAYS
GOING TO BE ONLY PART OF THE
STORY.
WHAT PEOPLE REMEMBER MORE ABOUT
SYLVESTER CROOM WAS HIS
PHILOSOPHY, HIS CONVICTIONS, HIS
CHARACTER, ALL OF WHICH STAYED
THE SAME FROM THE DAY HE WALKED
IN THE DOOR TO THE DAY HE LEFT.
>> HE REALLY WAS THE PERFECT GUY
TO BE FIRST.
THE WAY HE CARRIED HIMSELF, YOU
GRACE,UCH GLASS AND GRACE,UCH G
YET THAT FIERY BRIMSTONE, WE'RE
GOING TO DO IT MY WAY.
>> BECAUSE OF SYLVESTER CROOM,
THERE ARE THREE BLACK HEAD
FOOTBALL COACHES IN THE S.E.C.
>> I CAN REMEMBER THE NEWS
SYLVESTER CROOM JUST GOT HIRED.
FOR ME FROM THAT BACKGROUND,
THAT STANDPOINT, IT MOVED A
SITUATION YOU THOUGHT WAS NEVER
GOING TO HAPPEN INTO POSSIBLE.
I THINK IT HAS A DIRECT EFFECT
ON ME BEING THE HEAD COACH AT
TEXAS A&M TODAY.
>> HE WAS A PIONEER, HE WAS A
TRAIL BLAZER AND HE MADE SOME
VERY TOUGH DECISIONS.
BUT HE MADE THE RIGHT DECISIONS.
AND YOU CAN STILL SEE THE
FOOTPRINTS THAT SYLVESTER CROOM
LEFT AT MISSISSIPPI STATE TODAY.
♪
>> JUST LOOKING AT, DID YOU WIN
A NATIONAL CHAMPIONSHIP?
DID YOU WIN AN S.E.C.
CHAMPIONSHIP, THEN YOU MIGHT
LOOK AT IT AS A FAILURE.
BUT TO ME, I VIEW SYLVESTER AS A
GUY TWO WAS GREAT FOR FOOTBALL.
PERIOD.
>> HE CAME AND WENT QUICKLY.
AND WITH LITTLE FANFARE AT THE
END.
YOU HAVE TO LOOK AT THE WHOLE
PICTURE AND WHAT HE DID AND HOW
HE CHANGED THE GAME OF COLLEGE
FOOTBALL IN ITS GREATEST LEAGUE,
SIGNIFICANT AS THAT WAS IN '09
WITH BARACK OBAMA, THIS WAS
EQUALLY AS SIGNIFICANT WITH
SYLVESTER CROOM.
>> I HAVE BEEN VERY BLESSED TO
BE BORN INTO A FAMILY THAT I WAS
BORN IN, WITH THE GREAT
LEADERSHIP FROM MY MOTHER AND
FATHER, WITHOUT QUESTION,
EVERYTHING THAT I AM, EVERYTHING
THAT I BELIEVE IN, STARTED WITH
THEM.
BUT, YOU KNOW, I HAVE JUST BEEN
BLESSED.
ALL OF THE PEOPLE THAT I HAVE
BEEN -- THAT'S TOUCHED MY LIFE.
A GUY WROTE ME A LETTER THE
FIRST YEAR I LEFT MISSISSIPPI
STATE AND IN THE LETTER, IT
SAID, COACH, I'M GLAD YOU'RE
GONE.
YOU'RE A LOSER AND YOU ALWAYS
HAVE BEEN.
I WROTE A NOTE, I SAID, YOU
KNOW, SIR, WITH ALL OF THINGS
THAT I HAVE DONE IN MY LIFE, I
WISH YOU COULD HAVE THE SAME
FORTUNE THAT I HAVE HAD.
AND GOD BLESS YOU.
THEN I REALIZED IT WAS AN
ANONYMOUS NOTE, THERE WASN'T A
RETURN ADDRESS ON IT, SO I
COULDN'T SEND IT TO HIM.
BUT, THAT'S WHAT I FELT.
IF I'M A LOSER, THEN I HOPE YOU
HAVE THE SAME GOOD FORTUNE THAT
I HAVE HAD.
BECAUSE, I WOULDN'T TRADE IT FOR
ANYTHING.
♪
>>> WELCOME TO ESPN SPORTS
SATURDAY.
>>> HI, EVERYONE, I'M YOUR HOST
ROBERT FLORES.
AROUND THE COUNTRY ESPECIALLY
THOSE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
CONTINUE TO MOURN THE VICTIMS
AND FAMILIES AFFECTED BY
YESTERDAY'S SHOOTINGS.
ATHLETES ACROSS VARIETY OF
SPORTS TAKING TO TWITTER TO
EXPRESS THEIR THOUGHTS.
DREW BREES -- MY HEART BREAKS
FOR THE FAMILIES OF THOSE KILLED
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
IT IS SO SENSELESS.
I'M ANGRY.
>>> LeBRON JAMES TWEETING ONCE
AGAIN, OUR COUNTRY IS GOING
THROUGH ANOTHER HORRIFIC
TRAGEDY.
PRAYERS GO OUT TO ALL OF THE
FAMILIES IN CONNECTICUT.
I'M SICK.
ROBERT GRIFFIN III, I MAY NOT BE
A PARENT BUT I CANNOT BEGIN TO
IMAGINE HOW IT FEELS TO HAVE MY
CHILD'S LIFE TAKEN AWAY.
AND NO ONE EVER SHOULD.GHT, NBA
THEIR GAMES WITH A MOMENT OF  S
>> PLEASE JOIN US IN OBSERVING A
MOMENT OF SILENCE IN HONOR OF
THE VICTIMS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
>> THAT SCENE PLAYING ACROSS THE
LEAGUE AND JUST TODAY THE GIANTS
ANNOUNCING TODAY THEY'LL WEAR
SPECIAL HELMET DECALS TO HONOR
THE VICTIMS IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
FOR THE LATEST ON THIS TRAGEDY,
BE SURE TO GO TO ABCNEWS.COM.
AND UPDATES CONTINUE THROUGHOUT
THE DAY ON ABC AS WELL.
>>> RAY LEWIS IS NOT GOING TO
PLAY TOMORROW AGAINST THE
BRONCOS THAT ACCORDING TO SAL
PAOLANTONIO.
LEWIS RECOVERING FROM A TORN
TRICEP SUFFERED IN WEEKS SIX
AGAINST THE COWBOYS.
>>> SEVEN BIG EAST SCHOOLS THAT
DON'T PLAY FBS FOOTBALL ARE
LEAVING THE CONFERENCE, THAT
ANNOUNCEMENT TODAY, IT LEAVES
UCONN, CINCINNATI AND SOUTH
FLORIDA, THREE CURRENT MEMBERS
WITH FBS PROGRAMS.
>>> THIS WEEK IS ABOUT TAKING
CARE OF BUSINESS.
>> THIS IS CRITICAL WEEK.
>> ABOUT TO GET UGLY.
>> GET YOUR MIND RIGHT.
>> IT'S ABOUT PREPARING FOR THIS
GAME.
>> DO YOUR JOBS!
>> MAINTAIN OUR INTENSITY.
>> ONE, TWO, THREE -- WIN!
>> THERE ARE BIG GAMES ALL OVER
THE NFL DOCKET TOMORROW, THE
LATEST CALENDAR YEAR WITH SIX
GAMES WITH TEAMS WITH WINNING
RECORDS.
THE LATEST SUCH INTENSE,
DECEMBER 2003.
BIG GAMES.
PLAYOFF IMPLICATIONS ALL OVER.
1:00, PACKERS/BEARS.
BRONCOS AND RAVENS.
COLTS AND TEXANS, FIRST TIME
THIS SEASON.
GIANTS AND FALCONS.
49ers HEAD TO GILLETTE STADIUM
TO TAKE ON THE PATRIOTS 8:20
EASTERN, 5:20 PACIFIC.
HERE'S THE NFL 32 CREW BREAKING
IT DOWN.
>> THANKS, ROBERT.
ALONG WITH OUR NFL EXPERT, JASON
TAYLOR AND BILL POLIAN.
THIS IS CATCH 32.
WITH SIX GREAT GAMES THAT ALL
HAVE PLAYOFF IMPLICATIONS ON THE
LINE, HOW DO THE BEARS AVOID A
WEEK TWO REPEAT.
>> THIS IS VERY SIMPLE.
PLAY FUNDAMENTAL PLAYOFF.
RUSHING THE QUARTERBACK.
ALLOWED JAY CUTLER TO STAY
UPRIGHT.
THROW THE FOOTBALL.
ALLOW HIM TO HAND THE BALL OFF.
IF THEY CAN'T BLOCK AND THEY GET
JAY CUTLER BEAT UP, IT'S GOING
TO BE A LONG DAY FOR THEM.
>> EVEN IF THEY HAVE TO GO TO
EXOTIC COMBINATIONS LIKE TWO
TIGHT ENDS, THEY GOT TO KEEP HIM
UPRIGHT F THEY CAN'T X, IT WILL
BE A REPEAT OF WEEK ONE.
>>
>> HOW ABOUT ANDREW LUCK, HOW IS
GOING TO FARE AGAINST THE TEXANS
DEFENSE?
>> THROUGHOUT THE COURSE OF THE
SEASON, LUKE HAS PROVEN THAT
HE'S A GOOD QUARTERBACK.
HOWEVER, I THINK THE HOUSTON
TEXANS HAD A VERY, VERY
DIFFICULT WEEK LAST WEEK IN NEW
ENGLAND.
THEY'RE AT HOME.
A GOOD DEFENSE.
THEY'LL PUT A LOT OF PRESSURE ON
HIM.
IT WILL BE TOUGH.
I'M NOT SURE HE'LL FARE VERY
WELL.
>> I THINK THE COLTS ARE ABOUT
TO RUN OUT OF LUCK, PUN
INTENDED.
THE RUNNING IS GOING TO BE DONE
BY THE HOUSTON TEXANS IF THEY
CAN RUN THE BALL THEY CAN WIN
THIS GAME PRETTY HANDILY.
>>> HOW ABOUT THE MATCHUP TO
WATCH IN THE GIANTS AGAINST THE
FALCONS.
>> THIS IS GOING TO BE A GOOD
GAME.
THE FALCONS ARE SO OVERLOOKED.
THEY QUIETLY HAVE HAD A VERY
GOOD SEASON.
I THINK THE GIANTS SECONDARY HAS
KIND OF BEEN THEIR ACHILLES HEEL
AND THE X FACTOR IN THIS GAME.
PLENTY OF RECEIVERS, RUNNING
BACKING, VERY, VERY GOOD TIGHT
ENDS.
I LIKE THE OLDER GUYS, I LIKE
TONY GONZALEZ.
>> THE KEY FOR THIS GAME IS THE
FALCONS OFFENSIVE LINE, THEY GOT
TO PROTECT AGAINST THE NASCAR
RUSH.
IF THEY CAN DO THAT, MATT WILL
HAVE A GOOD GAME.
>> LAST TIME GIANTS WERE IN
ATLANTA, THEY WERE KNOCKING THE
FALCONS OUT OF THE PLAYOFFS.
>>> MEANWHILE, HOW MUCH OF A
DIFFERENCE WILL CALDWELL MAKE?
>> TO MAKE A CHANGE AT THE
OFFENSIVE COORDINATOR SPOT, I'M
CURIOUS TO SEE HOW THIS SPFANS
OUT.
HOW FLACCO RESPONDS TO THIS.
BILL
BILL KNOWS JIM CALDWELL LOT
BETTER THAN I DO.
>> OVER TIME, YOU'LL SEE MORE
UPTEMPO, MORE NO-HUDDLE, THAT'S
REALLY JIM'S EXPERTISE AND I
THINK THAT'S WHAT THEY WANT
FLACCO TO DO AND I THINK HE'S
ENTHUSIASTIC ABOUT IT.
>> THE QUARTERBACK WHO'S GOING
TO HAVE A BETTER GAME IN THE
STEELERS/COWBOYS MATCHUP?
>> I THINK BEN WILL BOUNCE BACK.
THEY'RE GOING INTO A TOUGH PLACE
TO PLAY IN DALLAS, BUT I THINK
THE DALLAS COWBOYS DEFENSE HAS
BEEN NOT VERY GOOD FOR THE LAST
FEW WEEKS AND BEN'S GOING TO GO
IN THERE AND HAVE A MUCH BETTER
DAY.
BEN, I LOVE THE WAY HE CREATES
PLAYS ON THE RUN.
>> I THINK BEN THE COWBOYS
DEFENSE HAS BEEN BEATEN UP
PRETTY BADLY, PHYSICALLY AND
THEY HAVEN'T BEEN GREAT ALL
SEASON, SO I LOOK FOR BEN TO
HAVE A BIG DAY.
>> AND THIS MIGHT BE ONE OF THE
MORE DIFFICULT QUESTIONS FOR
ANYONE TO ANSWER, HOW DO THE
49ers SLOW DOWN THE PATRIOTS
OFFENSE?
>> THAT'S A GOOD QUESTION.
>> I TOLD YOU --
>> YOU HAVE TO PRESSURE TOM
BRADY.
GET HIM TO MOVE OFF THE SPOT.
THE NINERS HAVE THE GUYS TO DO
IT.
THE SMITHS CAN COLLAPSE THAT
POCKET.
49ers STAY PHYSICAL, KEEP MIXING
IT UP, PRESSURE TOM BRADY, THEY
HAVE A CHANCE.
>> ALL OF THAT IS TRUE, YOU HAVE
TO KNOCK BRADY OFF THE SPOT.
THE OTHER THING THAT YOU HAVE TO
DO IS CONTROL THE BALL WITH THE
RUNNING GAME, HERE COMES FRANK
GORE AND THOSE BIG HUGS UP
FRONT.
>> THAT'S ANOTHER EDITION OF
CATCH 32.
NFL 32 AIRS WEEKDAYS AT 5:30 ON
ESPN2 ROBERT?
>>> THE PLAYOFF PICTURE IN THE
AFC.
BENGALS WIN THURSDAY, THEY JUMP
INTO THE FINAL PLAYOFF PICTURE.
THE STEELERS ARE OUT FOR NOW,
BUT THEY CAN GET BACK IN WITH A
WIN ON SUNDAY.
AFC NORTH BEING LED RIGHT NOW BY
BALTIMORE.
MEANTIME, NFC, THE FALCONS CAN
CLINCH HOME FIELD WITH A WIN AND
THE NFC EAST, THE GIANTS LOOKING
TO STAY ONE GAME UP ON THE
REDSKINS AND THE COWBOYS.
SPEAKING OF WHICH, COMING UP A
LITTLE BIT LATER, RG3 MAY BE
PLAY TOMORROW, SHOULD HE?
FIRST TAKE CREW ADDRESSING THAT
QUESTION LATER.
>>> IN THE NBA, THE LAKERS BEAT
THE WIZARDS, 102-96.
SNAPPING A SEASON-HIGH FOUR-GAME
LOSING STREAK, KOBE BRYANT, 40
POINTS, FIFTH CONSECUTIVE GAME
WITH AT LEAST 30.
LAKERS 2-11 WHEN BRYANT SCORES
AT LEAST 30.
HE WAS HOPING TO SEE THE
WASHINGTON JONGENERALS ON THEIR
SCHEDULE, EASY, KOBE.
SERIOUSLY, THE LAKERS ARE A TEAM
THAT WILL TAKE A WIN, BUT WHAT'S
NEXT FOR THIS STAR-STUDDED
COLLECTION?
THE NBA TONIGHT STUDIOS.
>> ROBERT, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
HERE WITH FLIP SAUNDERS, WELL,
FINALLY THE LAKERS FRIDAY NIGHT
GET OFF THE SCHNEID A LITTLE
BIT, THEY BEAT WASHINGTON IN THE
NATION'S CAPITAL.
FLIP, WE KNOW THAT THIS IS A
TEAM THAT HIRED MIKE D'ANTONI
BECAUSE IT'S CHAMPIONSHIP OR
BUST.
LET'S START WITH KOBE BRYANT AND
THE STARTING LINEUP, WHAT CAN
THEY DO TO FIX THE PROBLEMS AT
THE START OF THE BASKETBALL
GAME?
>> FIRST, THEY HAVE TO PLAY
TOGETHER.
THEY HAVEN'T TOGETHER VERY LONG.
THE SUCCESS IN NBA IS BEING
TOGETHER AND HAVING CONTINUITY.
THEY HAVE A LOT OF NEW PLAYERS
AND THEY HAVE A NEW SYSTEM.
BEGINNING OF GAMES, SENSE OF
URGENC
URGENCY.
EVERY GAME IS IMPORTANT.
WE GOT TO WIN A GAME.
WE GOT TO GET GOING.
GET A RHYTHM GOING.
THEY HAVE TO HAVE A SENSE OF
URGENCY, LOOK AT THE SCOUTING
REPORT AND KNOW WHAT THEIR
STRENGTH IS AGAINST THAT TEAM,
UTILIZE THEIR STRENGTHS.
>> A SEASON-HIGH 24 FOR HIM, HOW
IMPORTANT IS THIS BENCH GOING TO
BE GOING GUARD TO MAKE SURE THAT
KOBE DOESN'T HAVE TO PLAY 40
MINUTES A GAME?
>> IT'S IMPORTANT.
THE TEAMS THAT THEY HAVE TO BEAT
HAVE STRONG BENCHES.
L.A. CLIPPERS, ONE OF THE BEST
BENCHES IN THE LEAGUE.
SO, THE TEAMS THEY HAVE TO BEAT
HAVE VERY GOODS. BENCHES.
THEY HAVE TO GIVE THEM
PRODUCTION.
THAT'S WHAT MEEKS GAVE THEM ON
FRIDAY NIGHT.
HIS DEFENSIVE ENERGY THAT GOT
THE WHOLE TEAM GOING.
THEY CREATED SO MANY TURNOVERS,
19 TURNOVERS FRIDAY NIGHT.
>> ALL RIGHT, STEVE NASH HOPING
TO HAVE HIM BACK BY CHRISTMAS AT
LEAST, REALISTICALLY, HOW BIG OF
A DIFFERENCE IS HE GOING TO MAKE
WHEN HE'S IN THE LINEUP?
>> HE'LL BE A BIG DIFFERENCE.
IT WILL CUT DOWN ON THE
TURNOVERS.
THEY WON'T GIVE UP THOSE EASY
TURNOVER POINTS.
DEFENSIVELY WHERE THEY REALLY
STRUGGLED HE'S NOT GOING TO HELP
THEM VERY MUCH.
HE'LL HELP THEM WITH LEADERSHIP.
HE HAS GREAT INTELLECTUAL
KNOWLEDGE OF THE GAME.
MORE IMPORTANTLY, HE'S GOING TO
BE ABLE TO CONTAIN KOBE, HE'LL
GET INTO KOBE'S HEAD A LITTLE
BIT, GET HIM SOME EASY BUCKETS
WHEN HE NEEDS TO, SETTLE HIM
DOWN WHEN KOBE GETS ENERGIZED.
>> DWIGHT HOWARD DOESN'T SEEM
THE JOVIAL, OUTGOING GUY, WHAT
SHOULD THEY DO TO HELP HIM?
>> THEY HAVE BEEN GOING THROUGH
A LOT OF MISERY.
TO GET HIM GOING, GET HIM
TOUCHES AND GET HIS CONFIDENCE
GOING.
HE NEEDS TO RUN THE FLOOR AND
GET THE BALL ON THE SITUATIONS.
HE HAS TO STAY AGGRESSIVELY
DEFENSIVELY.
HE HAS TO BLOCK SHOTS, CONTROL
THAT TEAM.
>> THE LAKERS CONTINUE THEIR
ROAD TRIP IN PHILADELPHIA ON
SUNDAY, FOR FLIP SAUNDERS.
ROBERT, BACK TO YOU.
>>> LAKERS ARE STRUGGLING.
THE ROAD AHEAD ISN'T EASY.
THEY'RE 3-8 AWAY FROM STAPLES
CENTER THIS YEAR.
THEY'LL HOST THE KNICKS ON
CHRISTMAS DAY.
RIGHT HERE ON ABC.
WHO HAD THE SECOND BEST WINNING
PERCENTAGE THIS SEASON.
>>> STILL AHEAD -- THE TEXANS
DEFENSE EXPOSED MONDAY NIGHT
AGAINST THE PATS.
OUR COACH ERIC MANGINI SHOW YOU
WHAT HAPPENED AND HOW THE COLTS
COULD TAKE ADVANTAGE TOMORROW.
>>> AND THE FIVE THINGS YOU NEED
TO KNOW FOR WEEK 15, INCLUDING
WHY THE MOST DANGEROUS TEAM
PLAYING TOMORROW, JUST MIGHT BE
THE CLEVELAND BROWNS.
WAIT, WHAT?
>>> COUPLE WEEKS AWAY FROM THE
NATIONAL TITLE GAME, HOW WILL
THE QUARTERBACKS PLAY INTO WHAT
HAPPENS.
KIRK HERBSTREIT BREAKING IT
DOWN.
GETTING CASH BACK ON WHAT?
E AND HAIRCUT
FAN FOR THE CEILING.
YOU'RE GONNA COOL OFF
THAT HOOOOUNDDD!
TONIGHT YOU GOTTA GET YOUR
CASH BACK, ON NEW SLACKS.
USE FREEDOM ON LUNCH WITH JACK.
EVERYBODY GET! EVERYBODY GET!
GET YOUR CASH BACK.
CHASE FREEDOM.
[ Woman ]
♪ WHAT I WANT THIS SEASON
♪ IF YOU'D LIKE
TO TRY AND GUESS ♪
♪ IT IS SOMETHING VERY SPECIAL
♪ I WOULD READILY CONFESS
[ dogs barking ]
♪ 'CAUSE ALL I WANT
THIS SEASON ♪
♪ IS SOMETHING FROM YOUR HEART
♪ LA DA DA, LA DA DA
[ Male Announcer ] THINKING
OF OTHERS THIS HOLIDAY SEASON,
TRAVELERS.
>>> THIS IS ESPN SPORTS
SATURDAY.
>>> PLAY AUCTION.
SHOT DOWN FIELD FOR LLOYD,
TOUCHDOWN, PATRIOTS!
>> TOM BRADY AND JOSH McDANIELS
HAD AN AGGRESSIVE FIRST 15 TO
START THIS GAME.
>>> THE HOUSTON TEXANS
CONTROLLED VERY LITTLE MONDAY
NIGHT AGAINST NEW ENGLAND.
BUT THEY STILL CONTROLLED THEIR
DESTINY WHEN IT COMES TO PLAYOFF
SEEDING.
WIN OUT AND THE ROAD TO SUPER
BOWL IN THE AFC GOES THROUGH
HOUSTON.
BUT DEFENSIVELY THEY MUST
IMPROVE.
ERIC MANGINI SHOWS YOU HOW.
>> FOR ANDREW LUCK AND THE
INDIANAPOLIS COLTS TO MOVE THE
BALL AGAINST HOUSTON'S DEFENSE
THEY'VE GOT TO DO TWO KEY
THINGS, THEY CAN'T LET J.J.
WEATHER RUIN THE GAME AND THEY
HAVE TO FIND A WAY TO BEAT MAN
TO MAN COVERAGE.
HE'S LINED UP AS THE DEFENSIVE
END, WEATHER, THEY'LL TAKE THE
OFFENSIVE TACKLE AND THE TIGHT
END AND USE BOTH OF THEM AND
MAKE SURE THAT WEATHATT GET THE
EDGE.
YOU CAN SEE THEY'RE BEATING MAN
TO MAN COVERAGE ACROSS THE
BOARD, STAYING ON WATTOT
ALLOWING HIM TO GET TO BRADY.
WHAT NEW ENGLAND IS GOING TO DO,
THEY'RE GOING TO TAKE THE GUARD
HERE AND THE CENTER HERE AND
THEY'RE GOING TO BOTH FLY TO
WATT, MAKE SURE THHUURE THAT HE
PENETRATE AND NOW IT'S A
FUNCTION, CAN THEY BEAT MAN TO
MAN COVERAGE?
BRADY CAN STEP UP, HE'S ABLE TO
BEAT THE COVERAGE, ANOTHER
COMPLETION.
ANOTHER WAY THEY ATTACK THEM IS
WITH PLAY ACTION.
TWO-MAN ROUTE.
BRANDON LLOYD RUNS THE POST.
AARON HERNANDEZ RUNS THE WHEEL.
SPREAD WAX THE OFFENSIVE LINE.
HERE, TO THE BACK IS GETTING THE
BALL.
YOU CAN SEE BRADY SELL IT RIGHT
THERE.
THE SAFETIES ARE IN COVER FOUR,
THE SAFETIES DON'T HAVE ANYBODY
THAT THEY HAVE TO TAKE, THEY
SHOULD BE HELPING HERE ON
BRANDON LLOYD, BUT THE RUN
ACTION HAS THEM BOTH COME UP TOO
FAR WHICH MEANS NOW THAT LLOYD
IS ABLE TO GET INSIDE OF
JONATHAN JOSEPH RIGHT HERE AND
IT'S A BIG PLAY AND THE OTHER
THING THAT THIS DOES IS IT SLOWS
DOWN THE PASS RUSH AND IT SLOWS
DOWN J.J. WATT.
THEY WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT WATT
DOESN'T RUIN THE GAME.
AND THEY HAVE TO FIND ANSWER FOR
BEATING HOUSTON'S MAN TO
COVERAGE.
>> ERIC, THANK YOU.
>> HOUSTON'S ALLOWING A
LEAGUE-HIGH 336 YARDS PER GAME.
SO, THROUGH THEIR FIRST NINE
GAMES THIS SEASON THE TEXANS
WERE SECOND IN THE LEAGUE IN
TOTAL DEFENSE, ALLOWING JUST 281
YARDS PER GAME.
JOINED NOW BY OUR NFL ANALYST,
CHRISTIAN FORAY.
WE HAVE HEARD FROM TENS OF
PEOPLE.
THEY ENJOYED FIVE THINGS TO KNOW
SO MUCH.
>> LET'S SEE IF WE CAN GET SOME
MORE FANS.
STARTING WITH NUMBER FIVE, WHAT
THE BEARS ARE GOING THROUGH IS
WHAT BRAND YOUR MARSHALL SAID AT
HIS WEEKLY PRESS CONFERENCE.
CHECK THIS OUT.
>> OUR SEASON LOOKED LIKE THIS
TREE RIGHT NOW WHERE WE'RE
STANDING, JUST UGLY BUT, YOU
KNOW, THERE'S STILL HOPE.
>> GOOD GRIEF.
THE FACT, METAPHORICALLY HE'S
RIGHT.
THEY HAVE LOST FOUR OF THE LAST
FIVE, AFTER STARTING 7-1.
THEY DO HAVE A SHOT.
ALL THEY NEED TO DO IS WIN 2 OF
THE LAST 3.
>>> NUMBER FOUR, I KNOW THE MOST
DANGEROUS TEAM PLAYING ON SUNDAY
IS THE CLEVELAND BROWNS, THAT'S
RIGHT THE CLEVELAND BROWNS.
BEST WIN OF THE YEAR CAME LAST
WEEK AGAINST KANSAS CITY, THEY
WON 30-7, NOW THEY HAVE WON
THREE IN A ROW, NOW TRENT
RICHARDSON IS DOING GREAT JOB OF
RUNNING THE BALL.
THE WASHINGTON REDSKINS BANGED
UP AT QUARTERBACK, THIS COULD BE
A DANGEROUS TRAP GAME.
LOOK OUT.
>>> NUMBER THREE, LOTS OF TALK
ABOUT EXPANDING THE PLAYOFFS,
BUT I'M HERE TO TELL YOU THAT
IT'S A BAD IDEA, ADDING A COUPLE
OF WEEKS TO THE SEASON WON'T
MAKE THE REGULAR SEASON MORE
EXCITING.
BELIEVE ME, I HAVE DONE IT
BEFORE.
IT'S HARD TO2
PLAYOFF-CALIBER TEAMS AS IT IS.
I DON'T WANT ANYMORE OF A
WATERED-DOWN PRODUCT.
>>> NUMBER TWO, I KNOW THERE'S
LOT OF RECORDS HAVE A CHANCE TO
BE BROKEN OVER THE NEXT THREE
WEEKS.
ALVIN SMITH IS GOING TO MAYBE
BREAK MICHAEL STRAHAN'S RECORD.
AND YOU HAVE THE CALVIN JOHNSON
FOR THE SINGLE-SEASON RECEIVING
RECORDS.
AT ALL OF THEM, IT'S GOING TO BE
CALVIN JOHNSON IN RECEIVING.
>>> NUMBER ONE, STATISTICALLY
THE GIANTS AND THE FALCONS HAVE
THE BEST RECEIVING DUO IN THE
NFL AND THEY FACE EACH OTHER
TOSHL AND I'M HERE TO TELL YOU
THE BEST RECEIVING DUO AREN'T
EVEN RECEIVERS, THEY'RE TWO
TIGHT ENDS FROM THE NEW ENGLAND
PATRIOTS, ROBERT GRONKOWSKI AND
AARON HERNANDEZ.
HOW DO YOU COVER FROM THESE TWO
GUYS?
>> I HAVE TO GIVE TIGHT END LOVE
TO THE FORMER TIGHT ENDS.
LISTEN, DON'T GO ANYWHERE,
ANYBODY, WHEN I COME BACK, I'LL
TELL YOU WHY THE PATRIOTS WILL
CONTINUE TO ROLL AGAINST THE SAN
FRANCISCO 49ers WITH THE BEST
DEFENSE IN THE NFL AND I'M
BRINGING A LARGE FRIEND WITH ME.
>>> COMING UP, WE'RE JUST A
COUPLE OF WEEKS FROM THE COLLEGE
FOOTBALL CHAMPIONSHIPS.
WHAT SHOULD WE EXPECT FROM
McCARRON AND GOLSON?
KIRK HERBSTREIT BREAKS IT DOWN.
>>> YOU'RE WATCHING ESPN SPORTS
SATURDAY.
>>> YOU DO NOT COME TO THE
UNIVERSITY OF NOTRE DAME BECAUSE
YOU WANT TO BE AVERAGE.
>> UNIVERSITY OF ALABAMA, WE
WANT TO PLAY FOR THE TITLE EVERY
YEAR.
>> SETTLE BACK AND ENJOY, WE GOT
A GOOD ONE.
>> TOUCHDOWN, ALABAMA!
>> THE IRISH WIN THE GAME WITH
THEIR GREAT DEFENSE!
>> ALABAMA, IN ONE OF THE EPIC
COMEBACKS IN CRIMSON TIDE
HISTORY!
>> NOTRE DAME, SOMEHOW, FINDS A
WAY TO WIN AGAIN, ANOTHER
OVERTIME VICTORY.
>> I REALLY DIDN'T KNOW WHY.
NOW I KNOW WHY.
>> HE'S THROWING.
IT'S INTERCEPTED!
A&M GET IT.
LIGHTNING IN A BOTTLE IN
TUSCALOOSA.
>> NUMBER ONE AND NUMBER TWO,
BOTH LOSE.
>> GOAL-LINE STAND FOR THE AGES.
THE FIGHTING IRISH HAVE FINISHED
AN UNDEFEATED REGULAR SEASON.
>> ALABAMA WINS AND THE CRIMSON
TIDE WILL PLAY AGAIN AND THEY'LL
PLAY FOR ALL THE MARBLES!
>> THE BCS CHAMPIONSHIP, IT WILL
BE NUMBER ONE NOTRE DAME AGAINST
NUMBER TWO ALABAMA.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
LET'S DO THIS.
IT'S BEEN THREE WEEKS SINCE
NOTRE DAME LAST PLAYED.
TWO FOR ALABAMA.
BUT YET, IT ONLY FEELS LIKE 14
DAYS.
RIGHT?
PLAY THIS GAME ALREADY.
WAS THE FIRST OF MANY PREVIEWS,
RECE DAVIS AND KIRK HERBSTREIT.
>> LAST YEAR'S ALABAMA WIN WENT
INTO THE BCS CHAMPIONSHIP GAME,
A.J. McCARRON,CARRON, WAS LOOK
DON'T MESS IT UP, WHAT DO YOU
EXPECT FROM McCARRON AGAINST THE
FIGHTING IRISH.
>> LEADERSHIP.
POISE.
HE'S BEEN THROUGH THIS.
HE KNOWS WHAT TO ANTICIPATE AND
WHAT TO EXPECT IN THE NATIONAL
CHAMPIONSHIP.
HE'S QUARTERBACKING TWO S.E.C.
C
CHAMPIONSHIPS.
THE GREATEST THING THAT HE
BRINGS TO THE TABLE IS AN
ALABAMA TEAM THAT'S EXPERIENCED.
LET'S FACE IT, THEY WON IT IN 2
AGAIN, BECAUSE McCARRON HAS BEEN
AROUND ALL THAT, QUARTERBACKING
LAST YEAR'S TEAM AND THIS YEAR'S
TEAM, A VETERAN LIKE THAT AT A
KEY POSITION, IT CREATES AN AURA
AND CONFIDENCE ABOUT WHO YOU ARE
AND WHAT YOU'RE ABOUT TO
ACCOMPLISH.
>> NOTRE DAME AT THE QUARTERBACK
POSITION, IN THE EARLY PART OF
THE SEASON, THEY BROUGHT TOMMY
REES IN AS A CLOSER AT TIMES.
OVER THE LAST THREE GAMES, YOU
HAVE SEEN GOLSON GET BETTER,
PARTICULARLY THROWING IN THE
POCKET.
WHAT DO YOU EXPECT TO ASK
EVERETT GOLSON TO DO?
>> THE BIGGEST THING THAT HE HAS
TO DO HE HAS TO BE ABLE TO BE
AGGRESSIVE BUT AT THE SAME TIME,
HE HAS TO PROTECT THE FOOTBALL.
ALABAMA WILL TRY TO COME AFTER
HIM.
THEY'LL TRY TO GET PRESSURE AND
CREATE TURNOVERS.
EVERETT GOLSON HAS TO MATCH
THAT, NOT ONLY I HAVE TO PROTECT
THE BALL AND LET'S BE CAREFUL
AND PUNT, BUT HEY, WE'RE NOT
INTIMIDATED.
WE HAVE SEEN ALABAMA ON FILM.
EVERETT GOLSON HAS THAT BRAVADO
ABOUT HIM.
IT HAS TO BE DISPLAYED ON
JANUARY 7th.
I HAVE SEEN THIS GUY GROW.
I HAVE SEEN IT FIRSTHAND.
WE CALLED FOUR NOTRE DAME GAMES
IN PERSON.
TO SEE FROM DID BEGINNING OF THE
YEAR TO THE END OF THE YEAR,
IT'S LIKE WATCHING A DIFFERENT
GUY.
>> SEE IF EVERETT GOLSON IS
THEIEL, ALSO IN THE PROCESS, NY
GOLSON CAN KEEP McCARRON FROM
DOING, WIN BACK-TO-BACK BCS
CHAMPIONSHIPS AS A STARTING
QUARTERBACK.
>> ALL RIGHT, GUYS, AS WE WAIT
FOR THAT BCS NATIONAL TITLE GAME
AND THE OTHER BCS BOWLS, LET'S
GIVE YOU A TASTE OF SOME OF THE
OTHER BOWL GAMES THAT ARE WORTH
WATCHING.
>> WELCOME INSIDE THE COLLEGE
FOOTBALL STUDIO.
GENTLEMEN, OBVIOUSLY, NOTRE DAME
AND ALABAMA, NUMBER ONE BOWL
GAME THIS SEASON.
JOEY, WHAT'S THE BEST NON-BCS
BOWL OUT THERE.
>> I LIKE THE COTTON BOWL.
I LIKE THE MATCHUP OF THE
QUARTERBACKS.
JOHNNY MANZIEL, WINNER OF THE
HEISMAN TROPHY.
LANDRY JONES AT THE BEGINNING OF
THE SEASON, EVERYBODY WOULD HAVE
PUT HIM ON THE LIST, HAD A
PRETTY GOOD SEASON, ALL OF A
SUDDEN, THESE TWO MATCH UP IN
THE POSTSEASON.
>> PREVIOUS BIG 12-TYPE RIVALS.
ONE IS IN THE S.E.C.
MANZIEL WAS GOING TO BE A BETTER
QUARTERBACK THAN LANDRY OWENS
COMING INTO THE SEASON.
THE CHICK-FIL-A BOWL, LSU
AGAINST CLEMSON'S HIGH-POWERED
OFFENSE.
WE HAVE SEEN THEM PUT UP POINTS
BUT NOT UP AGAINST REALLY GOOD
DEFENSES.
CAN CLEMSON HOLD UP AND BLOCK
ANOTHER ACC/S.E.C. MATCHUP?
>> BOYD RUNS BETTER NOW.
>>.
>> IT'S A GOOD TEST OF COACHING.
ISN'T IT?
NOW YOU HAVE, YOU CAN'T HIDE
ANYWHERE.
YOU GOT THREE WEEKS AS A
COACHING STAFF TO PREPARE FOR
ONE PARTICULAR OFFENSE OR FOR
ONE PARTICULAR DEFENSE, DO THE
TRUE COLORS SHINE WHEN YOU GET
TO BOWL GAME?
>> YES.
LOT OF TIMES YOU'RE PLAYING
AGAINST AN OPPONENT THAT YOU
HAVE ABOUT SEEN ALL YEAR LONG.
IT'S NOT AN IN-CONFERENCE TEAM
THAT YOU PLAY YEAR IN AND YEAR
OUT.
IT'S NEW.
>> WITH BOTH OF THOSE MATCHUPS
THAT WE JUST TALKED ABOUT, TEMPO
IS A BIG THINGOKLAHOMA, OKLAHOMR
TEXAS TECH, CLEMSON, WHEN YOU
HAVE MULTIPLE WEEKS TO PREPARE
FOR THE TEMPO THE SHIFTS IN
FORMATION, AS A DEFENSE YOU
BECOME MORE COMFORTABLE WITH IT.
DEFENSES HAVE AN ADVANTAGE.
FOR OFFENSE IT'S ABOUT TIMING
AND RHYTHM.
>> ALSO THE ADDED ASPECT OF YOU
MIGHT BE SEEING SOME OF THESE
GUYS FOR THE LAST TIME OR MAYBE
NOT.
>> SOME OF THOSE GUYS KNOW
THEY'RE GOING TO THE NFL, STAY
AWAY FROM MY KNEES.
LET'S GET THIS OVER WITH.
DO WHAT YOU DO.
>> WE'LL KEEP AN EYE ON THOSE
BOWL GAMES.
>>> THURSDAY ZESPN, BYU/SAN
DIEGO STATE.
SAN DIEGO COUNTY CREDIT UNION
POINSETTIA.
8:00 EASTERN/5:00 PACIFIC.
>>> NOW BACK TO NFL, PAC
THE BEARS HAVE
THE BEARS HAVE THE OLDEST
RIVALRY IN THE LEAGUE, FOR GREEN
BAY, BEATING THEIR ARCH RIVALRY
HAS BECOME OLD HAT.
BUT THIS GAME ISN'T ABOUT THE
STREAKS OR THE NUMBERS.
BUT INSTEAD OF THE MEN THAT HAVE
PLAYED IN IT.
MIKE DITKA, JIMMY CRAMER
EXPLRIVALRY.
>> WHEN ARRIVED IN GREEN BAY, I
WAS TOLD BY ALL OF THE FANS IN
GREEN BAY THAT WE BETTER GET
READY FOR THOSE BEARS.
>> WHEN I CAME TO THE BEARS,
HEY, OUR GOAL WAS TO BEAT THE
GREEN BAY PACKERS.
>> WHEN I THINK OF THE BEARS, I
THINK OF VIOLENCE.
>> WE WANTED TO BEAT THEM AND
THEY WANTED TO BEAT US.
SO IT BECAME VERY, VERY INTENSE.
>> THE BEST IMAGE THAT COMES TO
MIND TO DESCRIBE A BEARS/PACKERS
GAME, IS THE OLD WESTERN SALOON,
ABOUT 50 PEOPLE IN THE MIDDLE OF
THE FIGHT AND EVERYBODY'S
HITTING EVERYBODY FROM EVERY
DIRECTION.
JUST AN OLD BARROOM BRAWL.
>> I JUST THINK THAT WE COMPETED
SO HARD AGAINST EACH OTHER, WE
TRIED TO KNOCK EACH OTHER OUT OF
THE GAME.
ACTUALLY TRIED TO DISABLED ME
AND I'M SURE I TRIED TO DISABLED
HIM.
>> I TRIED TO BUILD A HATE IN MY
MIND BEFORE BALL GAMES.
THERE WAS ALWAYS SOMETHING A
LITTLE EXTRA FOR THE BEARS.
THERE WAS ALWAYS BEAR WEEK AND
BEAR WEEK WAS MORE INTENSE THAN
ANY OTHER WEEK IN THE SEASON.
>> THERE'S NOTHING, NOTHING THAT
HE WANTED MORE THAN TO BEAT THE
GREEN BAY PACKERS.
>> IN THE PREGAME SPEECH, COACH
WOULD BE GETTING REALLY
EMOTIONAL AND REALLY EXCITED.
HE SAID, YOU GO OUT THERE AND
YOU KICK THOSE BEARS BACKSIDE.
>> WHEN YOU RESPECT SOMEBODY AS
MUCH AS WE RESPECTED THEM YOU
WANT TO BEAT THEM BECAUSE YOU
KNOW THE ONLY WAY YOU CAN GET TO
THE NEXT LEVEL IS TO BEAT THEM.
>> THEY SHOWED UP EVERY SUNDAY
AND THEY SHOWED UP FOR "60
MINUTES."
I HATE THEM BUT I LOVE TO PLAY
THEM.
ALIVE TODAY AS IT HAS EVER BEEN.
LOT OF INTENSITY ON THAT
FOOTBALL FIELD.
>> COMING UP NEXT -- OU RG3 MAY
BE PLAYING TOMORROW, BUT SHOULD
HE?
THAT'S NEXT AFTER THIS MESSAGE
AND A WORD FROM OUR ABC
STATIONS.
BEEN SHOPPING SO SMART, CASH
BACK WITH YOUR FREEDOM CARD
GETTING CASH BACK ON WHAT?
CLOSE SHAVE AND HAIRCUT
FAN FOR THE CEILING.
NA COOL OFF
YOU'RE GONNA COOL OFF
THAT HOOOOUNDDD!
TONIGHT YOU GOTTA GET YOUR
CASH BACK, ON NEW SLACKS.
USE FREEDOM ON LUNCH WITH JACK.
EVERYBODY GET! EVERYBODY GET!
GET YOUR CASH BACK.
CHASE FREEDOM.
[ Female Announcer ]
At Yoplait,
we want you to feel
even better
about your favorite flavors.
So when you call, tweet,
and post, we listen.
That's why Yoplait Light
and Yoplait Original
are now made with
no high fructose corn syrup.
And why we use
only natural colors
and natural flavors
in Yoplait Original.
So, anything else we can do
for you, let us know.
But you'll keep it
to yogurt, right?
'Cause we shouldn't really help
with your love life.
Yoplait. It is so good!
>>> FOLKS, WELCOME BACK TO
ESPN SPORTS SATURDAY.
THIS IS "NUMBERS NEVER LIE."
I'M MICHAEL SMITH.
HE'S JALEN ROSE.
WE'RE GOING TO TALK ABOUT WHY
I'M CONFIDENT IN THE COWBOYS AND
THE ANSWER IS TONY ROMO.
HE'S PASSED FOR AN NFL BEST
347.3 YARDS PER GAME AT HOME
THIS SEASON.
AND WHEN UNDER DURESS, AS HE'S
LIKELY TO BE AGAINST THE
STEELERS, HE'S THROWN AN
NFL-HIGH FIVE TOUCHDOWNS WITH A
TOTAL QBR 98.
JALEN, AM I CRAZY FOR PUTTING MY
TRUST IN ROMO AND THE COWBOYS
INSTEAD OF THE STEELERS?
>> YOU CAN PUT YOUR TRUST IN IT.
I DON'T THINK YOU SHOULD PUT ANY
MONEY ON IT.
I DON'T THINK THAT THE STEELERS
ARE GOING TO LOSE THIS WEEK
ESPECIALLY AFTER THE DEBACLE
THEY HAD THIS PAST WEEKEND.
THEY'RE GOING TO GET JAMES
HARRISON BACK AND TROY POLAMALU
BACK.
BOTH ON THE DEFENSIVE SIDE.
I EXPECT LAMARR WOODLEY TO GET
TWO SACKS AND I EXPECT BEN
ROETHLISBERGER SINCE RETURNING
FROM INJURY TO HAVE A BIG GAME.
>> THE LAST TIME I CHECKED, BEN
ROETHLISBERGER'S SHOULDER AND
RIBS ARE STILL SORE.
AND HELLO, DEZ BRYANT IS QUIETLY
BECOMING A CLUTCH RECEIVER.
THAT'S WHAT TONY ROMO NEEDS.
I'M GOING WITH THE DALLAS
COWBOYS.
>> SO CLUTCH THAT HE HAS A
BROKEN FINGER AND THAT HAS TO
PLAY A FACTOR FOR A RECEIVER
TRYING TO CATCH FOOTBALLS IN THE
NFL.
GETTING OFF THE GROUND, TRYING
TO BLOCK ON RUN PLAYS, IT'S
GOING TO BE VERY DIFFICULT TO
HIDE THE FACT THAT HE HAS A
BROKEN FINGER.
>> HE'LL BE OKAY.
TORRIDOL.
IT MASKS THE PAIN.
SUCK IT UP.
>> THAT'S GOING TO DO IT FOR US.
THIS IS THE KIND OF DEBATE THAT
YOU GET ALL THE TIME ON NUMBERS
NEVER LIE, CHECK US OUT EVERY
WEEKDAY AT 2:00 EASTERN ON
ESPN2.
NOW BACK TO MORE ESPN SPORTS
SATURDAY.
>>> WELCOME BACK TO ESPN SPORTS
>>> ROBERT AVOIDS ONE MAN.
HEADS UP THE FAR SIDELINE.
30, 35, TO THE 40.
HE'S TAKEN DOWN AT THE 40 YARD
LINE AND HE IS SLOW TO GET UP.
ROBERT'S NOT GETTING UP.
ROBERT IS STILL DOWN.
>> I KNEW AS SOON AS I GOT UP, I
SCREAMED, LIKE A MAN OF COURSE,
I KNEW I COULDN'T HELP THE TEAM
WIN ANYMORE.
AT SOME POINT YOU HAVE TO DO
WHAT'S RIGHT FOR THE TEAM.
I HAD TO GET OUT.
>> THE FACE OF THE WASHINGTON
REDSKINS IS A-OKAY, AS FOR HIS
KNEE, THAT'S ANOTHER STORY.
ROBERT GRIFFIN III LISTED AS
QUESTIONABLE FOR TOMORROW'S GAME
AGAINST THE BROWNS WITH THAT
SPRAINED KNEE.
CONSIDERING WHAT'S AT STAKE FOR
THIS SEASON AND BEYOND SHOULD HE
PLAY?
THAT'S WHAT WE ASKED THE "FIRST
TAKE" CREW.
>> THANKS, ROBERT.
LET'S EMBRACE DEBATE, RG3
PRACTICED ON THURSDAY AND
ACCORDING TO MIKE SHANAHAN HE
HAS IMPROVED FROM WEDNESDAY.
THE QUESTION IS SHOULD RG3 PLAY
ON SUNDAY?
SKIP?
YOU FIRST.
>> STEPHEN A., I GIVE UP.
YES, HE SHOULD PLAY ON SUNDAY.
>> WHAT?
>> I SAID EARLIER THIS WEEK, NO
WAY.
THAT LOOKED LIKE SUCH A SCARY,
BAD HYPERTENSION THAT HE
SUFFERED.
THANKS TO NGATA BENDING HIS KNEE
STRAIGHT BACK.
AND YET, ALL I HEAR OUT OF D.C.
IS, HE'S LOOKING BETTER AND
BETTER AND BETTER IN PRACTICE.
I'M STARTING TO THINK THAT RG3
IS BETTER THAN I THOUGHT.
HE'S A CARTOON CHARACTER.
THEY CAN'T BEAT CLEVELAND WITH
KIRK COUSINS AT QUARTERBACK.
I THINK THEY CAN MAKE THE
PLAYOFFS.
I THINK THEY CAN WIN OUT.
IF HE'S OKAY, I'M OKAY.
>> I DON'T CARE IF HE LOOKS LIKE
A SUPERMODEL, HE DOES NOT NEED
TO BE PLAYING THIS SUNDAY.
AFTER HE TOOK THAT HIT FROM
HALOTI NGATA, THE WAY YOU SAW
HIS LEG -- THAT WAS A
NASTY-LOOKING HIT RIGHT THERE.
IT WASN'T INTENTIONAL.
BUT YOU GET EXPOSED TO SOMETHING
LIKE THAT, I UNDERSTAND THAT
IT'S BETTER AND IT'S FEELING
BETTER.
BUT AT THE SAME TIME IT'S NOT
LIKE IT'S BEEN HIT AGAIN.
YOU NEED A BREAK, TAKE A WEEK
OFF.
RELAX, YOU'RE GOING UP AGAINST
THE CLEVELAND BROWNS.
YOU SHOULD BE ABLE TO BEAT THE
BROWNS THE KIRK COUSINS IS HAUL
THAT YOU SAID HE IS SUPPOSED TO
BE.
HE'S A QUALITY BACKUP.
HE CAME IN AND SEALED THE DEAL
AGAINST THE RAVENS.
WHY SHOULD YOU HAVE A PLAY
AGAINST THE CLEVELAND BROWNS?
EXCUSE ME, HOW MANY IN ROW HAVE
THE REDSKINS WON?
THEY HAVE WON FOUR IN A ROW.
>> WHY IS THAT?
>> ALL BECAUSE RG3.
>> ALL RIGHT, THAT AIN'T ALL.
THE FACT IS, THIS KID CAN STEP
IN AND GET THE JOB DONE.
THE SAME KID THAT YOU WERE
WORRIED ABOUT IN TERMS OF
REDSKINS DRAFTING HIM BECAUSE
OH, MY GOD, BECAUSE RG3 IS A
ROOKIE.
HE'S SENSATIONAL.
HE DOESN'T NEED TO HAVE THAT
THREAT HOVERING OVER HIM,
STEPHEN.
NO, THE FACT IS, THIS DUDE CAN
PLAY.
IF COUSINS CAN PLAY AND IS NO
THREAT TO RG3, HE'S IN THERE TO
SPELL RG3 UNTIL HE'S HEALTHY.
YOU NEED HIM FOR THE LAST TWO
WEEKS OF THE REGULAR SEASON
AGAINST PHILADELPHIA AND DALLAS.
YOU DON'T NEED TO BE WORRIED
ABOUT HIM AGAINST CLEVELAND.
BECAUSE IF YOU'RE WORRIED ABOUT
HIM AGAINST CLEVELAND YOU ARE
NOT WHAT I THOUGHT YOU WERE AND
WHAT THE GREAT ALL-KNOWING SKIP
BAYLESS SAID YOU ARE.
>> YOU'RE AFRAID THAT THE
REDSKINS ARE GOING TO CATCH THE
GIANTS AND WIN --
>> STOP IT.
STOP IT.
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT THE
REDSKINS.
STOP BRINGING BIG BLUE UP IN THE
MIX.
BY THE WAY, THEY ALREADY HAVE
THE LEAD IN THE NFC EAST.
>> ROBERT, WE'LL SEND IT BACK TO
HIM.
>> SIT AT HOME.
EAT SOME CAPTAIN CRUNCH.
>>> ALL RIGHT, GUYS, THANKS.
ROGER GOODELL, NFL COMMISSIONER
SPOKE EARLIER THIS WEEK ABOUT
THE POSSIBILITY OF PLAYOFF
EXPANSION.
FROM 12 TEAMS TO WHERE IT IS
NOW, TO MAYBE 14 OR 16.
16 WOULD BE HALF OF THE LEAGUE.
AND A HECK A LOT OF EASIER TO
GET INTO THE POSTSEASON.
THAN YOUR RUN-OF-THE-MILL
FANTASY LEAGUE.
MIKE AND MIKE DISCUSS.
>> ROBERT, THANKS.
MIKE AND MIKE HERE.
GOLIC, YEA OR NAY ON EXPANDING
THE PLAYOFFS?
>> I DON'T WANT TO.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT TEAMS AT
POSSIBLY 7-9 TO WIN A
CHAMPIONSHIP.
HALF OF THE TEAMS OUT OF THE 32
WILL GET INTO THE PLAYOFFS.
I'M COMPLETELY AGAINST IT.
>> I AGREE WITH YOU.
LY I'M AGAINST WATERING DOWN
REGULAR SEASONS.
BILL POLIAN MADE AN INTERESTING
POINT, THE MODEL IS 7 IN EACH
CONFERENCE.
ONLY ONE TEAM GETS A BYE.
MORE TEAMS FIGHTING FOR THAT
NUMBER ONE OVERALL SEED.
AND MORE TEAMS KEEPING THEIR
SEASONS MEANINGFUL DOWN NEAR THE
MIDDLE OF THE LOWER MIDDLE OF
THE PACK.
AGAIN, I'M AGAINST IT.
BUT CERTAINLY I COULD SEE SEVEN
LONG BEFORE I COULD SEE EIGHT.
>> ROBERT IS SMARTER THAN BOTH
OF US.
IT SHOULD MAKE IT THINK A LITTLE
BIT.
>> AND ROBERT IS SMARTER THAN
BOTH OF US COMBINED.
WE'LL SEND IT BACK TO YOU.
>> NO WAY THAT'S TRUE, FELLAS.
>>> COMING UP -- A HUGE WEEK IN
THE NFL.
WHO'S GOING TO WIN?
TAKE YOUR PICKS WITH OUR
EXPERTS, NEXT.
[ Woman ]
♪ WHAT I WANT THIS SEASON
♪ IF YOU'D LIKE
TO TRY AND GUESS ♪
♪ IT IS SOMETHING VERY SPECIAL
♪ I WOULD READILY CONFESS
[ dogs barking ]
♪ 'CAUSE ALL I WANT
THIS SEASON ♪
♪ IS SOMETHING FROM YOUR HEART
♪ LA DA DA, LA DA DA
[ Male Announcer ] THINKING
OF OTHERS THIS HOLIDAY SEASON,
TRAVELERS.
>>> THIS IS ESPN SPORTS
SATURDAY.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYONE.
I'M ROBERT FLORES.
PEOPLE AROUND THE COUNTRY
ESPECIALLY THOSE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, CONTINUE TO MOURN
AND REMEMBER THE VICTIMS AND
FAMILIES AFFECTED BY YESTERDAY'S
SHOOTING.
ATHLETES ACROSS A VARIETY OF
SPORTS TOOK TO TWITTER YESTERDAY
TO EXPRESS THEIR THOUGHTS.
THIS FROM SAINTS QUARTERBACK
DREW BREES -- MY HEARTS BREAKS
FOR THE FAMILY OF THOSE KILLED
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
IT IS SO SENSELESS.
I'M ANGRY.
DISGUSTED, BUT MOST OF ALL
EXTREMELY SAD.
>>> LeBRON JAMES TWEETING --
ONCE AGAIN OUR COUNTRY IS GOING
THROUGH ANOTHER HORRIFIC
TRAGEDY.
PRAYERS GO OUT TO ALL OF THE
FAMILIES IN CONNECTICUT.
I'M SICK.
>>> AND ROBERT GRIFFIN III, I
MAY NOT BE A PARENT BUT I CAN'T
BEGIN TO IMAGINE HOW IT FEELS TO
HAVE ANY CHILD'S LIFE TAKEN
AWAY.
AND NO ONE EVER SHOULD.
>>> LAST NIGHT NBA GAMES BEGAN
WITH A MOMENT OF SILENCE.
>> PLEASE JOIN US IN OBSERVING A
MOMENT OF SILENCE IN HONOR OF
THE VICTIMS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
>> THAT SCENE IN HOUSTON A SCENE
FAMILIAR ALL ACROSS THE LEAGUE.
>>> TODAY THE NEW YORK GIANTS
ANNOUNCING THAT THEY'LL WEAR
SPECIAL DECALS ON THE BACK OF
THEIR HELMETS FOR TOMORROW'S
GAME AGAINST THE ATLANTA
FALCONS.
FOR THE LATEST ON THIS TRAGEDY
GO TO ABCNEWS.COM.
UPDATES CONTINUE THROUGHOUT THE
DAY HERE ON ABC AS WELL.
>>> BACK TO THE ARENAS AND THE
FIELDS.
NUMBER ONE INDIANA AND BUTLER IN
OVERTIME.
INDIANA'S CODY ZELLER, 2 OF HIS
18 AT 86-86. TIES IT AT 86-86.
BUT THE BULLDOGS CALLED
TIME-OUT.
THIS IS WHAT THEY CALLED.
ALEX BARLOW, IN THE LANE, GOT
IT!
BUTLER TAKES OUT NUMBER ONE,
88-86, THEIR FIRST WIN AGAINST A
NUMBER ONE RANKED TEAM.
>>> THE GILDAN NEW MEXICO BOWL.
WHAT A FINISH THERE.
LESS THAN A MINUTE TO GO.
ARIZONA, NEED AN ONSIDE KICK,
THEY GET THE ONSIDE KICK.
WILDCATS IN BUSINESS.
NOW 22 SECONDS LEFT, FIRST AND
GOAL, MATT SCOTT TO TERRENCE
MILLER, GOT IT.
THEY OUTSCORED NEVADA IN THE
FOURTH QUARTER, ARIZONA WINS BY
ONE.
>>> IT'S A BIG WEEKEND AROUND
THE NFL SOME KEY GAMES WITH
PLAYOFF IMPLICATIONS.
LET'S PLAY A LITTLE TAKE YOUR
PICK.
AND FOR THAT, WE HAVE LOMAS
BROWN AND CHRISTIAN FAURIA.
WHO IS YOUR PICK, CHRISTIAN?
>> ALL RIGHT, I'M GOING TO TAKE
THE GREEN BAY PACKERS.
EVERYTHING COMING OUT OF CHICAGO
IS THAT THEY'RE TRYING TO GET
THE CULTURE CHANGED AND START
OVER AGAIN.
THEY STARTED 7-1, LOSE 4 OF THE
LAST 5.
I DON'T BELIEVE THEY HAVE ENOUGH
SKILL SET TO BEAT THE GREEN BAY
PACKERS.
THE LAST TIME THEY PLAYED, JAY
CUTLER WAS SACKED SEVEN TIMES.
HE'S BANGED UP.
AND THE OFFENSIVE LINE IS STILL
BANGED UP.
THEY'RE STILL ONLY THROWING TO
IT MARSHALL.
I GIVE IT TO GREEN BAY.
>> I'M GOING WITH GREEN BAY,
TOO.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
GREEN BAY IS STARTING TO GET
HEALTHIER.
CLAY MATTHEWS.
WOODSON.
THEY MIGHT BE COMING BACK.
THE OFFENSE OF GREEN BAY, THESE
GUYS ARE EFFICIENT.
THESE GUYS DO WHAT THEY HAVE TO
DO AND THEY ATTACK ZONES.
THE WEAKEST PART TO ME OF THE
CHICAGO BEARS' DEFENSE.
>> THEY HAVE A RUNNING GAME,
TOO.
>> IN OUR NEXT GAME, A PLAYOFF
REMATCH FROM LAST SEASON, THE
GIANTS BEAT THE FALCONS AT
METLIFE.
FALCONS SCORED JUST TWO POINTS
IN THAT GAME.
NOW THE FALCONS GET THEM AT
HOME.
START WITH YOU, LOMAS.
>> I GOT TO GO WITH THE G-MEN.
LOOK, THESE GUYS, IT'S THAT TIME
OF THE YEAR, WHERE MEDIOCRE
TEAM, A TEAM THAT HASN'T BEEN
PLAYING WELL, THAT'S WHEN THEY
START PICKING IT UP.
THAT'S WHAT THE GIANTS DO.
THE GIANTS GET VERY CONFIDENT
DURING THIS TIME.
>> COCKY.
ARROGANT.
>> NOT COCKY.
BUT THEY GOT THEIR REASON.
THEY GOT THEIR SUPER BOWL SWAG
FROM LAST YEAR.
THEY KNOW THEY CAN TURN IT ON
AND OFF, THIS IS THE TIME OF THE
YEAR THAT THEY GET READY TO TURN
IT ON.
I LOOK FOR THEM TO DOMINATE UP
FRONT.
>> I SAY YOU CAN'T TURN IT ON OR
OFF WHEN YOU FEEL LIKE IT.
I FEEL YOU NEED SOME
CONSISTENCY.
I'M PICKING THE FALCONS.
GOING BACK TO LAST WEEK AGAINST
THE CAROLINA, TWO BIG GAMES BY
CAM NEWTON HAD A BIG RUN.
DeANGELO WILLIAMS HAD A BIG RUN.
TWO BIG PLAYS THAT REALLY MADE A
DIFFERENCE IN THAT GAME.
ATLANTA, THIS IS GOING TO BE
THEIR, WE'RE NOT THE SAME OLD
FALCONS TEAM, OKAY?
GOING BACK TO LAST YEAR, THEY
LOST.
GREAT OPPORTUNITY FOR THEM TO
MAKE UP FOR LAST YEAR.
AND SHOW THE GIANTS AND THE REST
OF THE NFC THAT THEY'VE EARNED
THE NUMBER ONE SPOT.
FALCONS WIN AT HOME, AGAIN.
>> FROM THE NFC TO THE AFC AND
COLTS AND TEXANS MEETING FOR THE
FIRST TIME IN THREE WEEKS.
THEY'LL WRAP UP THE REGULAR
SEASON AGAINST ONE ANOTHER.
IN INDIANAPOLIS.
BUT TOMORROW, THEY MEET IN
HOUSTON.
CHRISTIAN'S REVERSE JINX WORKED
FOR THE PATRIOTS.
WHO ARE YOU TAKING TOMORROW IN
HOUSTON?
INDIANAPOLIS OR HOUSTON?
>> LISTEN, THIS TEAM PLAYING
WITH A LOT OF SPIRIT BUT I THINK
SOMETIMES THEY'RE OVERMATCHED AT
TIMES, BUT ANDREW LUCK HAS DONE
A GREAT JOB OF BRINGING THIS
TEAM BACK, HOWEVER THE HOUSTON
TEXANS EMBARRASSED.
IF YOU LOOK AT THAT TAPE,
THIS WAS A TEXAS TEAM THAT
PRETTY MUCH FAILED ON EVERY
IMPORTANT GAME SITUATION THEY
HAD.
FIRST TIME THEY HAD THE BALL,
OFFSIDE PENALTY.
FIRST RED ZONE OPPORTUNITY,
COULDN'T MATCH IT.
FIRST FUMBLED OPPORTUNITY TO
PICK IT UP THEY LOST IT.
THEY WEREN'T READY FOR THIS
GAME.
MAYBE IT WAS A LITTLE TOO BIG
FOR THEM.
I DON'T THINK THEY WERE
OVERMATCHED, WHEN YOU LOOK AT
IT, I THINK THE TEXANS OVERWHELM
THE INDIANAPOLIS COLTS.
>> WOW, YOU KNOW WHAT --
I'M GOING WITH INDY.
>> DON'T DO IT, LOMAS.
>> I'M GOING WITH INDY.
THIS TEAM RIGHT HERE THEY HAVE
MORE QUESTIONS THAN ANSWERS
RIGHT NOW, COMING OFF THAT
EMBARRASSING LOSS AGAINST THE
PATRIOTS.
THEY HAVE MORE QUESTIONS THAN
THEY HAVE ANSWERS FOR THEM.
I THINK THE INDIANAPOLIS COLTS,
VERY CONFIDENT TEAM.
WE KNOW ABOUT CHUCK PAGANO.
THEIR COACH.
THEY'RE USING THAT AS THEIR
INSPIRATION.
WE DID IT BACK IN '91.
I HEAD A TEAMMATE GET PARALYZED.
WE USED THE MOMENTUM TO GET TO
THE NFC CHAMPIONSHIP GAME.
THEY HAVE A ROOKIE QUARTERBACK
PLAYING LIKE A VET.
>> HE'S PLAYING ON BORROWED
TIME.
SIX TOUCHDOWNS, SIX
INTERCEPTIONS.
ONLY COMPLETED 40% OF HIS
PASSES.
>> BUT I SEE THE COACHING STAFF
LOOKING AT THAT.
I SEE THEM TWEAKING THE GAME
PLAN A LITTLE BIT.
LET HIM HAND IT OFF A LITTLE BIT
MORE.
>> THE TEXANS ARE ANGRY.
THE COLTS HAVE TO PAY.
>> ANOTHER BIG MATCHUP IN THE
AFC, THE BRONCOS AND THE RAVENS.
PEYTON MANNING HISTORICALLY HAS
PERFORMED VERY WELL AGAINST THIS
BALTIMORE GROUP.
TAKE YOUR PICK.
>> I'M GOING WITH THE BRONCOS.
I CAN'T GO AGAINST PEYTON
MANNING.
LOOK, TO ME ONE OF THE BEST
QUARTERBACKS AT PRESNAP READ.
IF YOU GO UP AS A DEFENSE, IF
THE RAVENS GET UP AND THEY SHOW
THEY LOOK TO PEYTON MANNING TOO
EARLY AND THIS GUY GETS A CHANCE
TO DISSECT IT, HE'S GOING TO EAT
THE RAVENS APART.
I THINK THE RAVENS ARE GOING TO
MISS RAY LEWIS.
YOU SAY, MISS RAY LEWIS, YEAH,
HE'S THEIR INSPIRATIONAL LEADER.
HE LINES THEM UP WHERE THEY NEED
TO BE LINED UP.
HE MAKES SURE THESE GUYS DON'T
STOP.
THEY GO UNTIL THE END OF THE
WHISTLE.
THAT'S MY PICK RIGHT THERE, THE
BRONCOS.
>> THAT'S THE SMARTEST THING
THAT YOU SIDE THE WHOLE SEGMENT.
I'M GOING TO AGREE WITH YOU, MY
LARGE FRIEND.
I'M GOING WITH THE BRONCOS.
YOU HAVE TWO DIFFERENT TEAMS.
THE RAVENS ARE TRENDING DOWN.
THE BRONCOS ARE TRENDING UP.
THEY HAVE BEEN PLAYING WELL,
SLOWLY PLAYING BETTER.
GETTING USED TO IS THE SYSTEM
THAT PEYTON MANNING HAS.
VON MILLER IS PLAYING
UNBELIEVABLE.
THE RAVENS, DEFENSIVELY, THIS
ISN'T THE SAME TEAM.
JOE FLACCO EVEN THOUGH THEY HAVE
A GOOD RECORD, NEEDS TO PLAY A
LITTLE BIT BETTER.
THEY CHANGED THEIR OFFENSIVE
COORDINATOR.
WHAT KIND OF A PHILOSOPHY CHANGE
ARE WE GOING TO SEE?
>> THAT'S BAD SIGN.
>> WHEN COW DO THAT THIS LATE IN
THE SEASON, DECEMBER, WHAT KIND
OF MESSAGE ARE ROW SEND DWROURG
TEAM?
>> IRONICALLY, JIM CALDWELL IS
THE OFFENSIVE COORDINATOR FOR
THE BALTIMORE RAVENS NOW.
MANNING'S OLD HEAD COACH.
>>> SAN FRANCISCO AND NEW
ENGLAND.
BOTH OF THESE TEAMS HAVE DESIGNS
ON PLAYOFF POSITIONS.
THE PATRIOTS WERE FANTASTIC AT
HOME ON MONDAY NIGHT.
TAKE YOUR PICK.
>> LAST WEEK I PICKED AGAINST
THE PATRIOTS.
I'M MORE SCARED ABOUT THE 49ers
THAN ANY OTHER TEAM.
I THINK THEY'RE GOING TO BE A
PHYSICAL MATCHUP THAT THE
PATRIOTS HAVE SEEN ALL YEAR.
THE 49ers DEFENSE ONLY ALLOWING
1.2 YARDS AFTER CONTACT.
WHAT DOES THAT TELL YOU?
THEY'RE PHYSICAL.
ONCE THEY HIT YOU YOU'RE NOT
BREAKING FREE.
IN THE END, IT'S TOM BRADY.
DECEMBER, STILL TRYING TO GET A
FIRST-ROUND BYE, NUMBER ONE SEED
IF POSSIBLE, IT MAY BE RAINY OR
SNOWY.
IT'S LATE AT NIGHT.
BIG STAGE.
A YOUNG QUARTERBACK FOR SAN
FRANCISCO ALSO.
>> YOU KNOW WHAT, I AGREE WITH
YOU, MY SMALLER FRIEND.
I AGREE WITH YOU ON THAT.
IT'S GOING TO BE TOM TERRIFIC.
I'M NOT GOING TO LOOK AT THE
OFFENSIVE SIDE OF THE BALL.
GUESS WHAT?
I'M GOING TO TALK ABOUT THEIR
DEFENSE.
BIG VINCE WILFORK CLOGGING UP
THE MIDDLE.
THAT'S WHAT THEY NEED.
WE DEFINITELY KNOW THAT SAN
FRANCISCO IS GOING TO GO WANT TO
COME OUT AND POUND THE BALL
BETWEEN THE TACKLES.
VINCE WILFORK CAN CONTROL THE
LINE OF SCRIMMAGE, IF HE DOES
THAT, THEY'LL ALLOW THE
LINEBACKERS TO STAY BACK AND
MAKE THEIR READS.
I LOVE NEW ENGLAND IN THAT GAME.
>> LOT OF PEOPLE HAVE BEEN
TALKING ABOUT J.J. WATT, THE
MOST UNDERRATED PLAYER THIS YEAR
SO FAR.
>>> REAL QUICK, STEELERS AND
COWBOYS?
WHAT'S YOUR PICK IN THAT ONE?
>> I'M GOING WITH THE COWBOYS,
THEY NEED IT.
IT'S A MUST-WIN FOR THEM.
>> I'M GOING WITH THE STEELERS.
THEY NEED IT BUT THEY'RE NOT
GOING TO GET IT.
>> BOTH TEAMS IN MUST-WIN
SITUATIONS.
AS THEY FIGHT FOR THE PLAYOFFS
IN THE NFC AND THE AFC.
>>> HERE'S WHAT YOU SHOULD BE
WATCHING FOR NEXT WEEK ON
MONDAY, HISTORY POSSIBLY, ESPN2,
ASSUMING SYRACUSE BEATS CANISIUS
TONIGHT, JIM BOEHEIM WILL HAVE
899 WINS GOING INTO MONDAY'S
GAME AGAINST DETROIT.
TRYING TO BECOME THE THIRD ALL
TIME WITH AT LEAST 900 DIVISION
WINS.
>>> TUESDAY, THE CELTICS HEAD TO
CHICAGO TO TAKEN TO BULLS.
THE CELTICS HAVE LOST 5 OF THEIR
LAST 6 IN CHICAGO.
THEY WON THERE EARLIER THIS
SEASON, RAJON RONDO WAS A
REBOUND SHY OF THE
TRIPLE-DOUBLE.
>>> WEDNESDAY, TWO NEW YORK
BURR BOROUGHS FACING EACH OTHER.
MSG HAS BEEN GOOD TO THE KNICKS,
CURRENTLY THE ONLY TEAM NOT TO
LOSE AT HOME THIS SEASON.
THE NETS HAVE WON THE LAST TWO
AFTER LOSING FIVE IN A ROW.
>>> CAPITAL ONE BOWL WEEK
CONTINUING THURSDAY WITH THE
POINSETTIA BOWL, BYU/SAN DIEGO
STATE.
AZTECS WITH A CHANCE AT AN
EIGHT-GAME WINNING STREAK.
SAN DIEGO WILL HAVE TO BEAT
BYU'S DEFENSE THAT RANKS THIRD
IN THE FBS.
>>> UPCOMING BOWL GAMES.
THERE'S THE SLATE THERE.
WRAPPING UP WITH THE SHERATON
HAWAII BOWL ON CHRISTMAS EVE.
THAT WILL DO IT FOR THIS EDITION
OF ESPN SPORTS SATURDAY.
THANKS FOR WATCHING.
I'M ROBERT FLORES.
WE'LL BE BACK NEXT SATURDAY
AFTERNOON.
ENJOY YOUR WEEK.
>> NEXT AT 5:00, BREAKING NEWS.
INVESTIGATORS SAY THEY FOUND
SOME VERY GOOD EVIDENCE THAT
WILL PROVIDE ANSWERS FROM
YESTERDAY'S SCHOOL MASS SIR.
>> A HORRIBLE THING.
YOU FEEL HELPLESS.
>> Ama: A TOWN COMING TO TERMS,
FINDING STRENGTH AND SUPPORT
DURING THIS TREMENDOUS TRAGEDY.
>>> LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE
GUNMAN, NEIGHBORS SHARE THEIR
INSIGHT
>> JUST A WHILE AGO.
>> YESTERDAY HE SAID, MY SCHOOL
IS DEAD, AND I THINK IN HIS WAY
IT IS.
IT'S NEVER GOING TO BE THE SAME.
>> THE TOWN IS RESILIENT.
WE'RE GOING TO COME BACK.
>> Ama: A SMALL TOWN IN
MOTHERING AFTER A SCHOOL TRAGEDY
IN CONNECTICUT.
TODAY WE LEARNED