IS THE BEST WAY
I CAN THINK OF
TO RUIN A PERFECTLY GOOD
MAI TAI.
OH, ARE YOU GOING
SOMEPLACE WARM?
WE DON'T
HAVE TO TALK ABOUT IT.
OH, NO. I WANT TO TALK
TO YOU ABOUT MY HONEYMOON--
THE HOTEL, THE SIGHTS...
I'M GONNA HANDLE
MRS. GELLMAN MYSELF.
WHAT I'M WEARING ON THE PLANE,
WHAT I'M WEARING ON THE BEACH.
LEAH, LEAVE.
AND THE WEDDING--SHOULD I
GET MY NAILS DONE TODAY
OR TOMORROW ON MY WAY
TO THE CEREMONY?
OKAY, SHE'S GONE.
I GOT THIS.
(ding)
(Meredith) THE ADRENAL SYSTEM
REACTS TO STRESS
BY RELEASING HORMONES THAT
MAKES US ALERT AND REACTIVE.
THE PROBLEM IS,
THE ADRENAL SYSTEM CAN'T TELL
WHAT'S A REGULAR CASE OF NERVES
AND WHAT'S
A REAL IMPENDING DISASTER.
YO, LEFKOWITZ.
DID YOU BRING IT?
(man) THAT'S THE WHOLE THING?
YEP.
LEFKOWITZ HAS GASTROPARESIS
SO HE CAN'T DIGEST HIS FOOD.
HE WAS AN EPIC PUKER
FOR A LONG TIME,
AND NOW HE CAN'T REALLY
EAT AT ALL.
SO WE'RE GONNA GIVE YOU
A GASTRIC NEUROSTIMULATOR.
(groans)
THIS THING,
IT'S GONNA ZAP YOUR STOMACH
SO IT REMEMBERS
TO PUSH THE FOOD
DOWN YOUR SYSTEM.
GET YOU BACK
ON BURGERS AND FRIES.
THAT'S AMAZING.
YEAH, WELL, THE GUYS
AT THE AIRPORT X-RAY
ARE GONNA GO NUTS.
THAT'S SICK.
OH, UH, THIS IS DR. WILSON.
SHE'S GONNA BE OPERATING
WITH ME.
YOU'VE GOT A-A CRACK TEAM,
IRON MAN.
(monitor beeps rhythmically)
(woman speaking indistinctly
over p.a.)
HEY.
♪ DUH, DUH, DUH-DUH
DON'T.
♪ DUH, DUH, DUH-DUH, DUH
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT.
I'LL STOP. I'LL STOP.
JEEZ.
WHEN YOU AND ARIZONA
GET TO THE WEDDING TOMORROW...
MM-HMM.
DON'T SIT DOWN.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
DON'T SIT DOWN?
JUST FIND A PLACE
AND STAND THERE.
YOU WANT US TO STAND
IN THE BACK?
THEN WE WON'T BE ABLE
TO HEAR ANYTHING.
STAND IN THE DAMN FRONT.
AND BLOCK EVERYBODY'S VIEW?
(sighs)
I MEAN, IF WE'RE--
I DON'T--
JUST PICK A SPOT.
YOU KNOW,
IT'S NOT COMPLICATED. UGH!
YOU KNOW, PEOPLE ALLOW YOU
TO OPEN THEM UP WITH A KNIFE.
IF THEY KNEW YOU COULDN'T
FOLLOW A SIMPLE INSTRUCTION,
THEY WOULD RUN LIKE THE WIND
FROM THIS PLACE. (exhales)
(elevator bell dings)
ARE YOU...
ARE YOU TRYING TO SAY,
"WOULD YOU DO ME THE HONOR
OF BEING MY BRIDESMAIDS?"
DOES THE WHOLE THING
HAVE TO BE ABOUT YOU?
JUST PUT ON A DRESS
AND DON'T SIT DOWN.
AWW. WE'RE BRIDESMAIDS.
OH, DON'T EVEN---
(squeals)
JU--JU--SEE? UGH.
THIS IS WHAT
I WAS TRYING TO AVOID.
OHH.
NOW ONCE I REMOVE
THE SURAL NERVE FROM YOUR LEG,
DR. TORRES WILL GRAFT IT ON TO
DR. SHEPHERD'S MEDIAN NERVE.
YOU'LL LIKELY EXPERIENCE
SOME DISCOMFORT
IN YOUR LEG FOR A FEW WEEKS--
MONTHS. MONTHS.
AND WHEN HE SAYS "DISCOMFORT,"
IT'S GONNA HURT LIKE HELL.
WELL, YOU'RE A BAG
OF SUNSHINE, AREN'T YOU?
I DON'T WANT TO HEAR
SIX MONTHS FROM NOW
THAT YOU CAN'T MOVE
AND THAT THE IBUPROFEN
HURTS YOUR STOMACH.
HE MAKES ME SOUND LIKE
I'M A 90-YEAR-OLD MAN.
HAVE YOU NOTICED THAT?
BECAUSE I'VE HEARD FOR DECADES
HOW I RUINED YOUR LIFE...
BECAUSE YOU DID.
AND THAT MOM DOESN'T LOVE YOU.
BECAUSE SHE DOESN'T.
I DON'T WANT TO HEAR
ABOUT THIS.
I THINK WHAT YOU'RE TRYING
TO SAY IS "THANK YOU, LIZZIE,
FOR CUTTING OFF A LEG
AND GIVING IT TO ME."
AH. HERE IT IS. THIS IS HOW
IT'S GONNA GO DOWN IN HISTORY.
IT IS A NERVE.
IT IS NOT THE ENTIRE LEG.
OKAY. LET'S FOCUS.
JACKSON.
UM, I THINK
DR. SHEPHERD'S RIGHT.
IF YOU'RE UNSURE, WE--
OH, COME ON.
I'M JUST WINDING HIM UP
BECAUSE IT IS SO EASY.
JUST GIVE ME THE FORM.
OKAY.
(clears throat)
NOW CAN I GO HANG OUT
WITH ZOLA IN DAY CARE?
OH, I'M SORRY.
THEY DON'T LET THE ADULTS
COME AND GO
BECAUSE IT'S HARDER
ON THE KIDS.
I WILL BRING HER TO YOU LATER.
(kisses)
(clicks keyboard keys)
GREY.
UH, WHEN YOU GET
TO THE WEDDING TOMORROW,
DON'T SIT DOWN.
(elevator bell dings)
(woman)
CALL FOR A PORTABLE ECHO.
THE LAWYER
PUT TOGETHER THE PAPERS.
THEY'RE GONNA
SEND THEM OVER TOMORROW.
OH, I SIGNED A BUNCH OF STUFF
WITH THEM LAST WEEK.
UH, NOT THE PLANE CRASH.
THE DIVORCE.
OH.
THAT WAS FAST.
I SAID WE WANTED
TO MOVE QUICKLY.
APPARENTLY.
IT'S ALL DONE.
YOU JUST HAVE TO SIGN.
(exhales)
IS THAT A PROBLEM?
NOPE.
TOMORROW, WITH A PEN.
(woman) OKAY.
EVERYTHING OFF
FROM THE WAIST DOWN.
NICE PAPER TABLECLOTH
FOR YOU. I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
YOU KNOW, UM...
I WAS THINKING ABOUT
TELLING LIZZIE
IF YOU'RE OKAY WITH THAT.
(door closes)
UM, I THINK
IT'S STILL KIND OF EARLY.
YEAH, BUT SHE'S DOING
THIS THING FOR ME.
SHE'LL TELL
YOUR WHOLE ENTIRE FAMILY.
WELL, YOU TOLD CRISTINA.
(jeans thud)
I HAVEN'T.
STILL?
THERE'S NO POINT.
I'M PROBABLY
GONNA MISCARRY ANYWAY.
MEREDITH--
I AM JUST STATING THE FACTS.
I HAVE
A VERY UNSTABLE UTERUS.
THIS BABY HAS
AN UPHILL CLIMB.
I AM JUST BEING REALISTIC.
(knock on door)
READY TO TAKE A LOOK?
YEAH.
(door closes)
(chair wheels clatter)
(exam table pieces clank)
OKAY, SCOOT DOWN.
NOW THERE'S STILL
A LOT WE CAN DO
TO SUPPORT THE PREGNANCY,
RIGHT,
EVEN WITH OUR HISTORY?
OF COURSE.
YOU'VE GOT SOME RISK FACTORS.
BUT WE'RE GONNA WATCH YOU
LIKE A HAWK.
OKAY.
(machine beeps)
(clicks keyboard key)
(beeps)
(clicks keyboard keys)
(fetal heartbeat
playing over monitor)
THERE WE GO.
HI, BABY.
(heartbeat continues)
Captioning provided by
ABC Studios, ABC, Inc.
and brought to you by Ford.
Go Further.
-- Captions by VITAC --
(people speak indistinctly)
♪
[ chirping ]
[ bleating ]
[ meowing, barking ]
[ Male Announcer ]
UNLIMITED PHONE...
UNLIMITED DATA...
UNLIMITED GIFTS OF JOY.
BUY ONE SAMSUNG GALAXY PHONE...
GET THE SAME MODEL FREE.
VISIT A SPRINT STORE
OR SPRINT.COM/HOLIDAY TODAY.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] CAMPBELL'S
GREEN BEAN CASSEROLE.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO
A LOWER PRICE ON YOUR GIFTS.
GETTING THEM HOME?
WOW.
YEAH.
THAT'S ANOTHER STORY.
CITI PRICE REWIND.
SEE HOW YOU CAN SAVE
AT CITI.COM/PRICEREWIND.
NESPRESSO.
WHERE I NEVER HAVE TO COMPROMISE
ON ANYTHING.
♪
WHERE JUST ONE TOUCH
CREATES THE PERFECT COFFEE.
WHERE EVERY CAPPUCCINO AND LATTE
IS ONLY MADE WITH FRESH MILK.
AND WHERE THE STAFF
IS EXCEPTIONALLY FRIENDLY.
♪
NESPRESSO. WHAT ELSE?
(jingles)
(laughs) GOOD NEWS.
ARIZONA AND I BOTH HAVE
RED DRESSES.
NOW THEY'RE NOT THE SAME,
BUT THEY ARE SIMILAR.
SO IT'S NOT LIKE MATCHY-MATCHY,
BUT IT'LL BE SUPER CUTE.
NOW WHICH PART OF MY FACE SAYS
I WANT SUPER CUTE?
OHH. GET OVER IT ALREADY.
IT'S A WEDDING.
NO ONE CARES THAT IT'S
YOUR SECOND OTHER THAN YOU.
JUST HOLD YOUR NOSE.
IT'LL BE OVER IN A FEW HOURS.
SURE.
AND THEN WE'LL BE MARRIED.
AND, OH, HIM IN L.A.,
ME HERE WITH MY SON
AND A JOB THAT'S KNOWN TO
TAKE UP A GREAT DEAL OF TIME.
OH, AND HE'S AN INTERN,
BECAUSE ONE SPECIALTY
WASN'T ENOUGH FOR HIM.
LET'S GET TO THAT PART.
HUH.
YOU KNOW, EVERYONE'S ACTING
LIKE I'M SOME JITTERY BRIDE.
MAYBE I HAVE SOMETHING
TO JITTER ABOUT.
WELL...
IF IT'S THE MARRIAGE
YOU'RE REALLY WORRIED ABOUT...
YOU CAN RUN.
EXCUSE ME?
LEAVE HIM AT THE ALTAR.
IT'S A CLEAN BREAK.
HE'S SO PISSED THAT YOU
STOOD HIM UP
IN FRONT OF ALL HIS PEOPLE,
THE WHOLE THING IS JUST OVER.
AND THEN YOU'RE NOT WRESTLING
WITH A RELATIONSHIP
THAT'S DOOMED
OR TIED TO SOMEONE
FOR THE REST OF YOUR LIFE.
I MEAN, SURE,
YOU LOVE EACH OTHER NOW.
BUT THE NEXT THING
YOU KNOW,
YOU ARE CLEANING
HIS PEE OFF THE GROUND
AND GOING TO BED
WITH A FOOT-WIDE
DEMILITARIZED ZONE
DOWN THE MIDDLE
OF THE BED.
(woman speaking indistinctly
over p.a.)
(inhales) KIDDING.
(laughs) I'M JUST KIDDING.
I'M KIDDING.
(elevator bell dings)
NO, IT--IT'LL BE FINE.
IT'LL BE FINE.
YEAH, BEN'S THE...
THE BEST. HE'S...
HE--
(pop version of "Silver Bells"
playing)
WE HAVE TO DO AN OPEN PROCEDURE
'CAUSE HE'S GOT ADHESIONS
FROM A SURGERY
A COUPLE YEARS AGO.
ONCE HE'S OPEN,
YOU CAN TAKE DOWN
THE ADHESIONS.
(exhales) REALLY?
YEAH.
I'VE NEVER DONE
ANYTHING LIKE THAT BEFORE.
YEAH, WELL, IF IT WAS ME,
I'D SPEND THE NEXT FEW HOURS
IN THE SKILLS LAB.
♪
DR. KAREV.
IS THIS BECAUSE
I TOLD YOU ABOUT
WHEN I WAS A KID?
OH, YEAH. I FEEL SO BAD YOU WERE
A DUMPSTER-DIVING ORPHAN,
I'M LETTING YOU
HACK UP A 10 YEAR OLD.
SORRY. STUPID.
YA THINK?
FLOWERS, MUSIC--
IT'S A RECIPE FOR DISASTER.
APRIL, YOU'RE GOING
TO BE FINE.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
OH, COME ON. DON'T TELL HER
SHE'S GONNA BE FINE.
YOU'RE GONNA BE
LOOKING ALL PRETTY,
LITTLE BIT OF LIP GLOSS
ON YOUR PRUDE-Y LITTLE MOUTH.
JACKSON WILL SPOT HER
ACROSS THE ROOM.
TRY TO LOOK AWAY,
BUT HE CAN'T.
YOU'RE IRRESISTIBLE
IN YOUR DRESS.
ONE DRINK, AND YOU'RE DOING
THE HIPPITY-DIPPITY
IN THE COAT ROOM.
THE DRESS? OH, GOD.
SEE?
CRUEL.
(cash register bell dings)
(woman) ♪ CHRISTMAS DAY
(clears throat)
WHAT?
NOTHING.
(indistinct conversations)
♪ STRINGS OF STREET LIGHTS
(Leah) SO HE'S INTO YOU NOW?
KAREV? NO.
UH-HUH. THEN WHY'S HE LETTING
YOU TAKE DOWN ADHESIONS?
HAVE YOU
EVER REMOVED ADHESIONS?
NO. NONE OF US HAVE.
(door opens)
(Arizona) HEY, WILSON.
UH, WHERE ARE SUJIN KIM'S
POST-OP NOTES?
I DIDN'T FINISH IT.
I WANTED TO PRACTICE FOR THIS
GASTRIC NEUROSTIMULATOR SURGERY
I'M DOING WITH DR. KAREV.
SHE'S TAKING DOWN
THE ADHESIONS.
REALLY? OH.
GOOD FOR YOU.
HE MUST REALLY TRUST YOU.
MM.
HMM. UM...
I HOPE YOU'RE NOT USING
BLUNT DISSECTION,
'CAUSE THAT'LL TEAR IT.
YOU WANT NICE, PRECISE MOVES
WITH THE INSTRUMENTS.
♪ SILVER BELLS
OKAY.
YOU SURE YOU'RE READY
FOR THIS?
YEAH. YOU WANT ME
TO GET YOU THAT CHART?
NO. IT CAN WAIT.
YOU SHOULD PRACTICE.
♪ RING-A-LING
♪ HEAR THEM RING
(door closes)
SEE? SHE SHOULDN'T EVEN
BE DOING A MOVE LIKE THIS.
HE'S INTO HER.
♪
THE LAST THING
YOU WANT AT YOUR WEDDING
IS TO WONDER IF MR. LINZER
IS CIRCLING THE DRAIN
JUST BECAUSE NOBODY
WAS MONITORING HIS I.N.R.
(elevator bell dings)
SO I'LL JUST STICK AROUND
HERE TOMORROW
AND KEEP AN EYE ON HIM.
KEPNER, YOU BROKE UP
WITH AVERY.
I--YES.
YES. I-I DON'T KNOW
WHAT THAT HAS TO--
YOU'RE AFRAID THAT
THE SIGHT
OF ME IN CREAM COLORED
RAW SILK
WILL BRING TEARS
TO YOUR EYES.
I AM SURE THAT YOU
WILL BE BEAUTIFUL--
I LOOK AT MY FATHER,
HE KISSES ME ON THE CHEEK,
I TURN AWAY FROM HIM,
TAKE A BREATH.
(woman) DR. WEBBER.
I STEP TOWARDS BEN...
IS THAT FOR ME?
HERE YOU GO.
THANK YOU.
AND YOU AND JACKSON LOCK EYES
FROM ACROSS THE ROOM.
YOU MELT INTO HIM
LIKE SNOW IN THE RAIN.
I KNEW
YOU WOULD UNDERSTAND.
SUCK IT UP, KEPNER.
IF I HAVE TO GO, YOU HAVE TO GO.
(elevator bell dings)
OKAY.
"IF I HAVE TO GO,
YOU HAVE TO GO"?
OH, DROP IT.
OH, NO.
THAT'S THE MOST BEAUTIFUL
SENTIMENT I'VE EVER HEARD.
(laughs)
(beeping)
LIZZIE'S CALVES
ARE A LITTLE SHORTER
THAN WE ANTICIPATED.
TALL GIRL, SHORT CALVES.
SO IS THAT GONNA BE
A PROBLEM?
NO, NOT IF WE JUST GET
A LITTLE MORE NERVE
FROM THE OTHER LEG.
(Derek) ARE YOU SAYING TO--
NO.
DEREK.
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
NO, I NEVER LIKED THIS IDEA
IN THE FIRST PLACE.
WE FIND ANOTHER DONOR
OR WE DON'T DO IT.
WELL, WE COULDN'T FIND
ANOTHER DONOR.
THAT'S WHY WE--
WELL, THEN WE'RE OUT OF LUCK.
CAN'T WE JUST--
NO, WE CAN'T. WE'RE NOT
GONNA TALK ABOUT THIS.
WE'RE NOT GONNA FLOAT THIS
PAST LIZZIE.
WE'RE NOT CUTTING BOTH HER LEGS
TO REMOVE PIECES.
CANCEL THE PROCEDURE.
HE IS A GOOD LITTLE MONKEY
AND ALWAYS VERY CURIOUS.
ONE DAY GEORGE GOT
AN IMPORTANT LETTER.
HE'S BUILT A ROCKET SHIP
TO TRAVEL INTO SPACE."
GOOGLE, HOW FAR IS EARTH
TO THE MOON?
THE MOON IS 238,900 MILES...
"THE GREAT MOMENT HAD COME."
3, 2, 1...
[ GIGGLING ]
YOU WANNA SEE IF WALMART HAS
SIMILAR GIFTS FOR LESS?
YEAH.
LET'S GO.
SAMSUNG GALAXY S3 --
OVER FIFTY DOLLARS LESS
THAN BEST BUY!
WOW! FIFTY BUCKS!
YEAH!
THAT'S A PAIR OF SHOES.
SEE FOR YOURSELF IF YOU COULD
SAVE ON THE GIFTS YOU WANT.
WALMART.
SEE FOR YOURSELF IF YOU COULD
SAVE ON THE GIFTS YOU WANT.
I THINK YOU SHOULD BRING
A DATE TO DR. BAILEY'S WEDDING.
THAT WAY WE WILL
FOCUS ON OUR DATES
AND NOT ON EACH OTHER.
OR WE COULD JUST BE FOCUSED
ON THE HAPPY COUPLE.
(woman) THANK YOU.
I AM WEARING
A STRAPLESS DRESS.
FROM HERE UP,
I'M COMPLETELY NAKED.
JUST...
WEAR A DIFFERENT DRESS.
I DON'T HAVE A DIFFERENT DRESS.
I WORK LONG HOURS.
I DON'T SHOP.
I HAVE--I HAVE
ONE DRESSY DRESS.
HOW AM I SUPPOSED TO FIND
A DATE WITH ONE DAY'S NOTICE?
(sighs)
(elevator bell dings)
STEPHANIE.
HEY.
UM, WOULD YOU LIKE TO GO
TO DR. BAILEY'S WEDDING?
OH, WHAT?
DR. AVERY WOULD LOVE
FOR YOU TO GO WITH HIM.
THAT'S NOT TRUE.
HE THINKS THAT YOU'D BE
EMBARRASSED,
BUT YOU'RE NOT EMBARRASSED,
ARE YOU?
OF COURSE SHE'S EMBARRASSED.
SHE'LL GET OVER IT.
LOOK, DON'T GET OTHER--
STRAPLESS...
AND TIGHT.
(indistinct conversations)
I WILL PICK YOU UP
AT 1:00 TOMORROW
IN THE LOCKER ROOM.
(elevator bell dings)
WHAT JUST HAPPENED?
WHAT ABOUT YOU?
YOU GOT TO PICK MINE,
SO I GET TO PICK YOURS, RIGHT?
JACKSON.
OH.
WHAT ABOUT SHANE?
HE'S A GOOD-LOOKING
PIECE OF MAN, HUH?
THEY'RE THAT SHORT?
(Meredith) NO, THEY'RE
PERFECTLY RESPECTABLE CALVES.
(laughs)
IT'S JUST THAT WE'RE NOT
GONNA GET QUITE ENOUGH NERVE
FROM JUST THE ONE.
(laughing) OKAY.
I KNOW
IT'S A LOT TO ASK.
NO, IT'S, UH, FINE.
DO WHAT YOU NEED TO DO.
DEREK THINKS
IT'S TOO MUCH TO ASK,
BUT HE REALLY NEEDS THIS,
SO IF HE COMES TO YOU AND TRIES
TO TALK YOU OUT OF IT,
YOU HAVE TO PUSH.
BUT DON'T TELL HIM THAT
I'M THE ONE THAT CAME TO YOU,
BECAUSE HE WON'T LIKE THAT.
(people speaking indistinctly)
YOU'VE GOT SOME BALLS,
DON'T YOU?
YOU KNOW, IF IT'S TOO MUCH,
WE CAN CALL THE WHOLE THING OFF.
YOU KNOW WE'RE FAMILY,
RIGHT?
THERE WAS NO WEDDING,
MEREDITH.
YOU ADOPTED A BABY
AND YOU NEVER INVITED US
TO COME MEET HER.
YOU NEVER ACCEPTED
OUR INVITATION TO COME SEE US.
ALL WE GOT WAS A COUPLE
OF PICTURES VIA E-MAIL.
YOU KNOW, MY KIDS WERE
SO EXCITED THAT FOR MONTHS,
THEY WALKED AROUND TELLING EVERY
AFRICAN-AMERICAN PERSON THEY SAW
THAT WE HAVE A BROWN BABY
IN THE FAMILY? (chuckles)
A YEAR LATER, THEY KIND OF THINK
I MADE THE WHOLE THING UP.
I'M SORRY.
IT'S JUST, YOU KNOW,
WITH EVERYTHING
THAT'S BEEN GOING ON--
NO, I GET THAT WE'RE ALL BUSY,
BUT YOU'RE NOT SHY ABOUT ASKING
ME FOR A COUPLE OF BODY PARTS,
AND NOW YOU WANT ME TO COVER
YOUR TRACKS WITH DEREK?
IF YOU FEEL LIKE
IT'S INAPPROPRIATE, WE--
NO, IT'S WHAT SISTERS
ASK SISTERS TO DO.
WE COVER EACH OTHER'S ASSES.
LOOK, IF YOU WANT TO BE
A SISTER,
I AM DELIGHTED,
BUT THEN ACT LIKE ONE.
(chuckles)
MY VERSION OF FAMILY
ISN'T LIKE YOUR VERSION.
YOU GUYS GIVE EACH OTHER CRAP
AND THEN YOU LAUGH ABOUT IT.
YOU'D WALK THROUGH FIRE
FOR EACH OTHER.
GREYS ARE NOT LIKE THAT.
DEREK SAID YOU HAD A SISTER
WHO WORKED HERE.
HALF.
SHE WAS ON THE PLANE?
YOU KNOW, I-I REALLY DON'T
WANT TO TALK ABOUT MY SISTER.
MY HUSBAND REALLY NEEDS THIS,
SO YOU DON'T HAVE TO LIKE ME,
JUST--JUST HIM.
YOU HAVE A CHILD.
SHE'S PART OF MY FAMILY.
YOU OF ALL PEOPLE
SHOULD REALIZE,
YOU NEED SPARES IN A FAMILY.
YOU NEED
AS MANY AS YOU CAN GET.
IT WAS VERY NICE
TO TALK TO YOU, LIZZIE.
HEY.
(elevator bell dings)
I STASHED A LITTLE JOHNNIE
IN CASE THE CEREMONY'S GOT
SOME COUSIN READING A POEM.
RIGHT.
UH, I MEANT TO FIND YOU.
I'M KIND OF BRINGING
A DATE.
YEAH, ME.
TWO GUYS PICKING UP
BRIDESMAIDS FROM OUT OF TOWN.
APRIL'S CONVINCED THAT IF WE
DON'T BOTH BRING DATES,
THEN WE'RE BOTH GONNA
END UP...
WHY YOU GOTTA TALK
TO HER?
SHE RUINS EVERYTHING.
HOW ABOUT I FIND SOMEONE
FOR YOU TO GO WITH?
YOU KNOW, MAYBE STEPHANIE
HAS A FRIEND.
STEPHANIE?
THAT'S WHO YOU'RE TAKING?
(bell dings)
YOU WANT A DATE OR NOT?
(doors open)
NO.
ALL RIGHT.
(indistinct conversations)
OKAY. WHATEVER.
JUST DON'T GET ME
AN UGLY ONE.
(indistinct conversations
continue)
WE'RE NOT DOING
THE PROCEDURE.
(scoffs)
OF COURSE WE'RE DOING IT.
YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
WHEN I SAID I'D DO THIS?
MOM CALLED ME THREE TIMES
IN ONE DAY.
(imitates voice breaking) IT
JUST BRINGS TEARS TO MY EYES.
SHE'S A MESS.
(normal voice) COME ON.
YOU'RE THE GOLDEN CHILD.
THE REST OF US ARE JUST
SCRAPPING FOR SECOND POSITION,
AND I JUST PUT
A LOCK ON IT FOR LIFE.
YOU THINK I'M GIVING THAT UP
JUST 'CAUSE YOU HAVE TO CUT
INTO TWO LEGS INSTEAD OF ONE?
LIZZIE--
NO, WE'RE NOT DISCUSSING IT.
I'VE DECIDED.
GET BACK ON THE HORSE,
DEREK.
OH, OKAY. SO YOU THINK I'M
USING THIS AS AN EXCUSE,
THAT I'M TOO SCARED TO TRY
AND OPERATE AGAIN?
NO, OF COURSE NOT.
NOTHING SCARES YOU.
MM.
WHAT IF IT DOESN'T WORK?
HMM? WHAT IF WE
GO THROUGH ALL OF THIS
AND NOTHING COMES OF IT?
WELL, THEN
AT LEAST WE TRIED.
WE'RE DOING IT.
JUST... SAY THANK YOU.
YOU READY?
YEP.
BOVIE, PLEASE.
(exhales)
THANK YOU.
OKAY, HERE?
YEP.
TAKE YOUR TIME.
OKAY.
(sizzling)
WATCH OUT
FOR THE BLOOD VESSELS.
WOW. LOOK AT YOU,
ALL GROWN-UP.
UP IN THE SKILLS LAB,
I WAS DOING--
(monitor beeping erratically)
YOU PUT A HOLE
IN HIS STOMACH.
I HAVEN'T EVEN--
MOVE, NOW. MOVE.
ALL RIGHT. CLAMP.
(woman) HERE YOU GO.
2.0 VICRYL.
(woman) I'LL GET IT.
SUCTION.
(woman speaking indistinctly
over p.a.)
HEY, STEPH.
YOU OKAY THERE?
FINE.
TERRIFIC.
I WANTED TO ASK YOU--
I WAS GONNA GO
TO THE WEDDING WITH,
YOU KNOW, A FRIEND--
A GUY, LIKE, STAG.
YEAH?
AND NOW HE FEELS LIKE
I'M BAILING ON HIM.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO GO
WITH ME.
NO, NO.
YOU DON'T WANT TO GO?
(singsongy)
YOU HAVE A DATE WITH GUY.
I DITCHED HIM, AND I WANT YOU
TO FIND SOMEBODY FOR HIM.
IS THAT WEIRD?
(normal voice)
NOTHING ABOUT THIS IS WEIRD.
TERRIFIC.
MM-HMM. MM.
(elevator bell dings)
(Alex) THERE'S STILL
SOME SPILLAGE.
GIVE ME SOME LAP PADS...
(monitor beeping erratically)
AND SOME 2.0 SILK.
GET OVER HERE
AND GRAB THE RETRACTOR
SO WE CAN PUT
THE DEVICE BACK IN.
WILSON.
I CAN'T GET MY HANDS
TO STAY STILL.
WELL, SHAKE IT OFF
AND GET OVER HERE.
THE KID'S GONNA BE FINE,
JUST GRAB
THE DAMN RETRACTOR.
(beeping continues)
GET OUT.
GO!
(beeping continues)
(panting)
YOU THINK BAILEY WILL NOTICE
IF I'M NOT THERE?
(scoffs) SHE JUST MADE YOU
A BRIDESMAID.
OH, SHE DOESN'T CARE
ABOUT ALL OF THAT.
SHE JUST WANTS A BUNCH OF PEOPLE
STANDING UP THERE
SO IT WON'T LOOK WEIRD
WHEN BEN HAS ALL HIS GUYS
STANDING UP THERE.
AND I HAVE A PACKED DAY
TOMORROW.
YEAH, 'CAUSE YOU'RE GOING
TO A WEDDING.
YOU'RE
SUPPOSED TO WEAR HEELS...
TO A FANCY OCCASION.
OH, COME ON.
NO, THEY MAKE YOU FEEL
TALL AND CONFIDENT
AND FEMININE AND--
AND MY PLASTIC FOOT ISN'T
THE RIGHT SHAPE FOR... HEELS.
I DIDN'T GET THAT KIND.
WELL, I MEAN--
IT'S NOT NOTHING.
I MEAN, WHY DO YOU THINK WOMEN
ALL OVER THE WORLD WEAR THEM?
BECAUSE WOMEN ALL OVER
THE WORLD ARE STUPID.
OH, OKAY. SO YOU'RE
GONNA WEAR FLATS?
OH, I'D BE HAPPY
TO WEAR FLATS.
OH, NO, YOU WOULDN'T BECAUSE
THEN YOU WOULD FEEL DUMPY.
OH-HO. DID YOU
JUST CALL ME DUMPY?
(laughs)
CAN YOU JUST
FOR ONE SECOND ADMIT
THAT YOU KNOW WHAT IT IS
I'M TALKING ABOUT?
OKAY, I KNOW IT'S HARD.
IT'S HARD ALL THE TIME,
AND THIS IS JUST
ONE MORE REMINDER.
BUT YOU ARE SO,
SO BEAUTIFUL.
YEAH,
PEOPLE STAND NEXT TO YOU
AND IMMEDIATELY
FEEL BAD ABOUT THEMSELVES.
IT'S A PUBLIC SERVICE
THAT YOU'RE
A COUPLE OF INCHES SHORTER.
IT IS A KINDNESS
TO EVERY OTHER WOMAN
AT THAT WEDDING
THAT YOU ARE JUST
ONE TINY BIT LESS BEAUTIFUL.
(chuckles)
MM-HMM.
YEAH.
(mouths word)
(sighs)
ARE YOU STILL MAD AT ME
BECAUSE I CALLED LIZZIE?
DO YOU STILL LOVE ME?
(chuckles) MEDIUM.
I JUST WANT YOUR HAND
TO BE BETTER
SO THAT WE CAN PUT THIS STUPID
PLANE CRASH STUFF BEHIND US.
WELL, THE LAWYER CALLED
TO SCHEDULE A DEPOSITION.
HE THINKS
WE HAVE A STRONG CASE,
ESPECIALLY NOW THAT CRISTINA
AND OWEN ARE GETTING DIVORCED.
WHAT DOES THAT HAVE TO DO
WITH ANYTHING?
WELL, IT'D BE A BIG
CONFLICT OF INTEREST
IF OWEN WAS MARRIED
TO ONE OF THE PLAINTIFFS.
THAT'S WHY THEY GOT DIVORCED,
RIGHT? SHE DIDN'T TELL YOU?
NO. WHY WOULD SHE NOT
TELL ME THAT?
YOU DIDN'T TELL HER
YOU WERE PREGNANT.
MAYBE THINGS
ARE DIFFERENT NOW.
(exhales)
HELLO?
[ Sea ] HI!
THIS IS THE SEA CALLING.
WHEN'S THE LAST TIME
YOU VISITED ME?
WHEN I WENT SURFING.
I LOVE TO SURF.
CAN YOU IMAGINE
SURFING IN THE MIDDLE OF ME?
IN THE MIDDLE OF YOU?
OH YES!
[ giggles ] NICE MOVES!
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
OUR BIGGEST DECEMBER
SALES EVENT EVER.
GOING ON NOW.
CALL 1-800-ROYAL-CARIBBEAN.
HI.
DELUXE DREAM VILLAGE.
THAT'S MY FAVORITE.
[ Male Announcer ] SOME PEOPLE
REALLY LOVE THEIR JOBS.
OK.
HAVE A SUPER SPARKLY DAY!
AND SOME PEOPLE
JUST LOVE TO SAVE MONEY.
SEE HOW YOU CAN SAVE
AT CITI.COM/PRICEREWIND.
HURRY IN AND TRY
FIVE SUCCULENT ENTREES,
LIKE OUR TENDER SNOW CRAB
PAIRED WITH
SAVORY GARLIC SHRIMP.
JUST $12.99.
COME INTO RED LOBSTER
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
SALADS, SANDWICHES, AND MORE.
AND IExcuse me, Maestro?CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
Bring it down, please?
Better. That's what happens to
background noise,
when you're making
a call on this.
This microphone here, picks up
the sounds around you and helps
turn them down.
So when the world gets noisy
Calls sound better.
(bell dings)
ON THE MORNING
OF YOUR WEDDING?
OH, MY HOUSE IS FILLED
WITH MY FAMILY
TALKING ABOUT MAKEUP
AND HAIR.
JUST CHECK INTO A HOTEL.
(woman) DR. BAILEY.
TAKE A NICE LONG BATH,
GET A MANICURE.
OH, NOW I GOT YOU
TALKING ABOUT MAKEUP AND HAIR?
DR. BAILEY, WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
CHECKING UP ON MY PATIENTS.
MAKING SURE YOU HAVEN'T
BUNGLED ANYTHING.
DON'T MENTION HER HAIR.
WHY? DID SOMETHING
HAPPEN TO YOUR HAIR?
(elevator bell dings)
OH.
HE PROBABLY KNEW
IT WAS RISKY,
SO HE WANTED IT ON ME
AND NOT HIM.
YOU HAVE TO STOP.
YOU'RE MAKING YOURSELF CRAZY.
I'M GONNA GET FIRED.
NO, YOU'RE NOT.
JUST KEEP YOUR HEAD DOWN
AND DO YOUR WORK.
(sighs) YOU'RE RIGHT.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
(man shouts indistinctly)
NOW I HAVE TO
ASK YOU SOMETHING,
AND IN LIGHT OF THE FACT
THAT YOU THINK YOUR JOB
IS ON THE LINE,
IT'S GONNA SOUND
REALLY STUPID.
WHATEVER. IT'S OKAY.
(sighs)
DR. AVERY ASKED ME
TO DR. BAILEY'S WEDDING.
AND I CAN'T PUT
TWO WORDS TOGETHER
INTO A SENTENCE
WHEN I'M WITHIN 2 FEET OF HIM,
AND HE'S BRINGING A FRIEND,
AND HE ASKED ME
TO BRING A FRIEND,
AND IT'LL BE
LIKE A BUNCH OF US,
AND WE'LL ALL GO TOGETHER.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
IT SOUNDS REALLY STUPID.
(sighs)
BUT WILL YOU DO IT?
(whiny voice) PLEASE, JO.
SOMEBODY PAGE CARDIO?
(clears throat)
YEAH, G.S.W. TO THE CHEST.
(monitor beeping rhythmically)
WE PUT UP 2 AND A HALF LITERS
OF BLOOD
WHEN WE
PUT IN THE CHEST TUBE.
(beeping continues)
WE SHOULD MOVE HIM UPSTAIRS.
THERE IS A BULLET
IN THE ABDOMEN.
I CAN DO IT, OR WE CAN CALL
FOR SOMEBODY ELSE.
YOU CAN DO IT.
AMICABLE, RIGHT?
MM-HMM.
LET'S MOVE.
(people speaking indistinctly)
YOU'RE STILL RECHECKING
KEPNER'S WORK?
WHAT I WAS BORN TO DO.
(clicks mouse)
I HAVE A CHOLE
IN ABOUT TEN MINUTES.
IN AND OUT, THE WHOLE THING
SHOULD TAKE AN HOUR.
YOU WANT TO SCRUB IN?
TAKE THE EDGE OFF BEFORE
YOU GO HOME AND GET DRESSED?
(sighs)
YOU... ARE A GOOD MAN.
DR. WEBBER.
OH, THE MAN OF THE HOUR.
OH, TELL ME YOU'RE NOT HERE
TO TAKE ME BACK TO THAT HOUSE.
(laughs) NO, I'M--I'M NOT.
OKAY, WELL, HE, UM, JUST ASKED
ME TO DO A CHOLE WITH HIM...
(voice breaking)
AND IT'S THE ONLY THING
THAT'S CALMED ME DOWN
ON A DAY FULL OF PEOPLE
TRYING AND FAILING
TO CALM ME DOWN.
WHY DO YOU THINK
HE ASKED YOU?
YOU CALLED HIM?
OH.
THANK YOU.
(laughs)
BOTH OF YOU.
SO CAN I HAVE A CAR
PICK YOU UP AT THE HOUSE?
HOW MANY TIMES DO I HAVE TO
SAY NO TO THAT?
A PERSON SHOULDN'T
DRIVE THEMSELVES
TO THEIR OWN WEDDING.
WELL, I LIKE TO DRIVE.
IN A WEDDING GOWN?
Y--IT'S MY LAST TEN MINUTES
AS A SINGLE WOMAN.
YOU KNOW, YOU BOTH
WERE ON A ROLL THERE.
WHY ARE YOU TRYING
TO SCREW IT UP NOW?
I'LL SEE YOU IN THE O.R.
AND I WILL SEE YOU
AT THE ALTAR.
(exhales)
DR. ROBBINS.
YEAH. HI.
DR. KAREV HAD ME TAKE DOWN
THE ADHESIONS.
YEAH. YEAH, HOW'D THAT GO?
SOME OF THE ADHESIONS
WERE STUCK TO THE STOMACH.
THE STOMACH WAS INJURED.
HE COULD BE SEPTIC BY NOW.
I DON'T THINK HE HAD
ANY BUSINESS
HAVING AN INTERN
DO THAT KIND OF MOVE.
I MEAN, YOU WERE PRETTY SHOCKED
TO HEAR THAT I WAS DOING IT.
HE THREW ME IN THE DEEP END,
PROBABLY BECAUSE--
OKAY, HANG ON.
WHAT EXACTLY ARE YOU SAYING
ABOUT YOUR ATTENDING?
(woman speaking indistinctly
over p.a.)
(sighs) G.S.W.
SWEET.
SCRUBBING IN WITH OWEN,
WHO WANTS TO SIGN
OUR DIVORCE PAPERS TODAY.
I GUESS WE'RE BEING
MATURE AND MOVING ON.
SPEAKING OF WHICH,
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME
THAT THE DIVORCE WAS BECAUSE
OF THE PLANE CRASH LAWSUIT?
WHAT?
DEREK TOLD ME, SO THAT
THE CASE IS STRONGER.
WHICH IS GREAT, I'M GLAD,
ESPECIALLY IF IT MEANS
THE TWO OF YOU
ARE GETTING BACK TOGETHER.
IT'S GOOD NEWS,
AND I DON'T KNOW
WHY YOU WOULDN'T WANT
TO SHARE THAT WITH ME?
BECAUSE I DIDN'T KNOW.
(sighs) YOU READY?
WHAT?
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
TAKE NOTES ON THE SPOT.
CATCH EVERY DETAIL
WITH VIDEO ZOOM.
♪
AND NOW RUN TWO APPS
AT THE SAME TIME
ON THE SAME SCREEN.
THE FREEDOM TO DO WHAT YOU WANT
WHEN YOU WANT.
LET'S GO AGAIN.
[ Male Announcer ] WITH THE
QUAD-CORE-POWERED LG OPTIMUS G.
AVAILABLE ON AT&T.
♪
BUT KISSING
IS AT AN ALL-TIME HIGH!
I WANT ANSWERS!
♪
OH. RIGHT.
KAY.
[ Female announcer ] IT'S TRUE,
EVERY KISS DOES BEGIN WITH KAY.
WHERE YOU CAN SAVE 25%
ON ANY BULOVA WATCH.
BULOVA. DESIGNED TO BE NOTICED.
AT KAY, THE NUMBER-ONE
JEWELRY STORE IN AMERICA.
♪
OHHHH. RIGHT.
♪ EVERY KISS BEGINS WITH KAY
she doesn't
Even though our really get us.
And she'll never know
who we are, or what...
No way,
Madden Girls??
Nike!
Who's your mommy now?
Famous brands. Famously easy.
Famous Footwear.
Victory is Yours.
YOU WANNA SEE IF WALMART HAS
SIMILAR GIFTS FOR LESS?
YEAH.
LET'S GO.
SAMSUNG GALAXY S3 --
OVER FIFTY DOLLARS LESS
THAN BEST BUY!
WOW! FIFTY BUCKS!
YEAH!
THAT'S A PAIR OF SHOES.
SEE FOR YOURSELF IF YOU COULD
SAVE ON THE GIFTS YOU WANT.
WALMART.
SEE FOR YOURSELF IF YOU COULD
SAVE ON THE GIFTS YOU WANT.
DR. SHEPHERD'S PREPPED?
YEP.
UH, DR. TORRES IS GOING OVER
THE STUDIES.
OKAY.
YEAH.
HOLD IT TOGETHER.
WELL, A NERVE EXTRACTION'S
A PRETTY SIMPLE PROCEDURE.
NOT THAT.
HE ASKED ME ON A DATE,
TO DR. BAILEY'S WEDDING.
DR. KEPNER ASKED ME.
IT'S A DATE?
IT'S NOT, LIKE,
A MENTORING THING?
HOW IS DRINKING CHAMPAGNE
AND DANCING TO BARRY WHITE
A MENTORING THING?
I THOUGHT IT WAS, LIKE,
SPENDING TIME
GETTING TO KNOW THE INTERNS
IN A CASUAL,
STRESS-FREE ENVIRONMENT.
THAT WAS THE FREE-DOUGHNUTS
THING IN THE LOUNGE.
(elevator bell dings)
THIS IS A WEDDING.
(groans) I CAN'T
GO ON A DATE WITH MY BOSS.
I NEED TO FOCUS ON MY WORK,
NOT GET ALL WRAPPED UP
IN THE LADIES.
DID YOU REALLY JUST SAY
"THE LADIES"?
YOU'RE THE ONE WHO JUST SAID
YOU COULDN'T CONCENTRATE
IN THE O.R.
'CAUSE DR. AVERY MIGHT LOOK AT
YOU WITH HIS LIMPID GREEN EYES.
THE EYES ARE REALLY INTENSE.
YOU'VE NOTICED IT YOURSELF,
RIGHT?
GET A GRIP.
YOU GET A GRIP.
KAREV, DID YOU TELL WILSON
THAT SHE'D BE FIRED FOR
SCREWING UP A GASTRIC IMPLANT?
WHAT?
IS THE PATIENT GONNA MAKE IT?
THE PATIENT'S FINE.
WHAT THE HELL DID SHE TELL YOU?
SHE THINKS THAT YOU SET HER UP
TO TAKE THE FALL
ON A RISKY O.R. PROCEDURE,
AND IT KIND OF SOUNDS LIKE
YOU DID.
IT WOULD'VE BEEN RISKY
NO MATTER WHO DID IT.
AND I WAS STANDING RIGHT THERE.
THE SECOND IT GOT HAIRY,
I TOOK OVER.
SHE WAS IN OVER HER HEAD.
AND WHERE DO YOU THINK
I GOT THE IDEA
TO DO SOMETHING LIKE THAT?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
YOU. I'M TRYING TO BE
LIKE YOU WERE WITH ME.
YOU LET ME TRY CRAP
SO I GOT CONFIDENCE IN MYSELF.
THAT'S WHAT I WAS TRYING TO DO--
NOT TREAT THE STUPID MORONS
LIKE THE STUPID MORONS
THAT I THINK THEY ARE.
I GAVE YOU OPPORTUNITIES.
I ALSO GAVE YOU A BOATLOAD OF
ENCOURAGEMENT AND SUPPORT.
I DIDN'T DROP-KICK YOU INTO
THE DEEP END OF THE POOL...
(lowered voice)
AND YELL, "SWIM, IDIOT."
YOU'RE A TEACHER NOW.
YOUR STUDENTS FAIL,
YOU'VE FAILED.
(sighs)
(groans)
(chart thuds)
OH!
GLAD YOU'RE DRIVING
YOURSELF TO THE WEDDING.
REMIND ME
TO STAY OFF THE ROADS.
(sighs)
WERE YOU LIKE THIS?
ON MY WEDDING DAY,
I REMEMBER STARING AT MY SOCKS
FOR A LONG TIME.
I HAD NO IDEA
WHAT TO DO WITH 'EM.
YOU KNOW,
TEN YEARS FROM NOW,
IF THE MARRIAGE IS STRONG,
I'LL LOOK BACK AT TODAY
AND SAY...
"IT WAS JUST A LITTLE BIT
OF COLD FEET."
IF WE'RE IN A NASTY DIVORCE,
I'LL SAY,
"I KNEW IT WAS A MISTAKE
THE DAY WE GOT MARRIED."
YOU THINK IT'S A MISTAKE?
I JUST FEEL...
WORRIED.
I NEVER FELT THAT WAY
WITH TUCKER.
YOU WERE A CHILD
WHEN YOU MARRIED TUCKER.
YOU'RE AN ADULT NOW.
YOU KNOW THE WORLD'S
AN AMBIGUOUS PLACE.
YOU KNOW THAT LOVE
DOESN'T CONQUER ALL.
IT CONQUERS SOME STUFF.
THE OTHER STUFF KICKS
THE LIVING CRAP OUT OF LOVE.
AND THIS IS THE PEP TALK?
(chuckles)
OVERWHELMING DOUBT
IS A PROBLEM.
A LITTLE BIT OF DOUBT
IS JUST A SIGN
OF AN INTELLIGENT ADULT.
IS GREY GONNA BE
IN THE GALLERY?
NO. SHE DIDN'T WANT
TO MAKE YOU NERVOUS.
(Callie chuckles)
I TOLD HER
YOU DON'T GET NERVOUS.
YOU'RE RIGHT. I DON'T.
CLOSE YOUR EYES.
ENJOY YOUR NAP.
YOU'VE GOT NOTHING
TO WORRY ABOUT.
MM.
(monitor beeping rhythmically)
TORRES.
HMM?
YOU'VE GOT NOTHING
TO WORRY ABOUT.
(laughs)
(hisses)
(exhales)
(monitor beeping rhythmically)
WE GOOD TO GO?
YES, WE ARE.
YES. WE'RE--YES.
(Meredith) Jackson,
I just want to let you know,
I'll be here watching
the whole time.
COULDN'T BE HAPPIER.
No mistakes.
THAT'S THE PLAN.
OKAY.
(clattering)
Are you kidding me?
GET THAT WOMAN
OUT OF MY GALLERY.
THAT'S NOT A GOOD IDEA.
GET HER OUT.
I heard that, Avery. Edwards,
don't even think about it.
(beeping continues)
NOW.
Edwards, you wouldn't dare.
You have years with me.
I can be very difficult
to deal with.
15-BLADE, PLEASE.
(Alex) YOU NARCED ON ME
TO MY BOSS?
I WORKED HARD TO GET HERE.
I'M NOT GONNA LET MYSELF
GET FIRED BECAUSE--
NOBODY'S FIRING YOU.
I WAS TRYING TO HELP YOU.
I CLEARLY WASN'T READY
FOR IT.
WHY, BECAUSE I HAD TO
TAKE OVER?
LOOK, YOU CAN'T GO CRYING
TO MY DAMN BOSS
EVERY TIME YOU GET SCARED.
YOU CAN'T CRY AT ALL
WHEN YOU GET SCARED
BECAUSE IT'S SCARY IN THERE
ALL THE TIME.
I JUST THOUGHT,
MAYBE AFTER I BLEW THE APPY,
I'D BE A GOOD TARGET
IF YOU NEEDED TO PIN SOMETHING
ON SOMEONE.
IT'S PARANOID. I GET THAT.
I DON'T ALWAYS TRUST PEOPLE
WHO ARE TRYING TO HELP ME.
YEAH, YEAH,
YOU'RE A BEATEN DOG
AND YOU BITE PEOPLE
WHO TRY TO FEED YOU.
I DON'T GIVE A CRAP
ABOUT YOUR SAD STORY.
YOU WANT TO BE A SURGEON, YOU
NEED TO GET THE HELL OVER IT.
YOU BURNED A BRIDGE WITH ME.
HOW ABOUT YOU GROW UP
BEFORE YOU BURN A BRIDGE
WITH EVERY OTHER ATTENDING
WHO TRIES
TO TEACH YOU SOMETHING?
50 CENTIMETERS
OF PRIME NERVE.
GREAT.
ALL RIGHT.
FORCEPS, PLEASE.
THANK YOU.
OKAY.
IS NO ONE MAKING SMALL TALK
BECAUSE THIS IS DEREK SHEPHERD
ON THE TABLE?
THIS IS INTRICATE WORK.
SMALL TALK
IS WHAT KEEPS US AWAKE.
WELL, UH...
A COUPLE OF DAYS AGO,
I HELPED DR. KEPNER
EXTRACT A MALIGNANT MASS
FROM THE GLUTEAL AREA
OF A FEMALE PATIENT.
(monitor beeping rhythmically)
IT--IT WAS
AN IMPRESSIVELY SIZED MASS.
WHO'S GONNA TELL DR. SHEPHERD
THAT HE'LL NEVER OPERATE AGAIN
BECAUSE ROSS' IDEA OF GOSSIP IS,
HE SAW APRIL KEPNER
TAKE A LUMP OFF AN ASS?
(beeping continues)
(instruments clink)
BROOKS, SUCTION.
(suction gurgles)
ALL OF, NOT HALF OF IT.
SORRY.
(gurgling)
HE'S GOT A BUNCH
OF TATTOOS.
WONDER IF IT'S SOME SORT
OF A GANG THING.
I HAD--
THE CHATTER ISN'T HELPING ME,
AND YOUR EXPERIENCE
WITH GANGLAND YOUTH
HAS LITTLE BEARING
ON HOW WE TREAT THIS PATIENT.
(gurgling continues)
(turns water off)
(pedal clanks)
WHAT THE HELL WAS THAT?
I THOUGHT THIS WAS
SUPPOSED TO BE AMICABLE.
WE'RE GETTING DIVORCED
BECAUSE OF THE LAWSUIT?
IT WILL SIGNIFICANTLY
INCREASE YOUR CHANCES--
YOU DIDN'T WANT
TO MENTION IT?
I WANT YOU TO GET THE MONEY.
I WANT ALL OF YOU
TO GET THE MONEY,
AND I KNEW THERE WAS
A VERY REAL CHANCE
THAT YOU WOULD REJECT THE IDEA
SIMPLY BECAUSE
I SUGGESTED IT.
OH, RIGHT. BECAUSE I'M
SO SIMPLE-MINDED AND PETULANT.
YOU'VE BEEN KNOWN TO--
WHERE DO YOU GET OFF
MAKING SOME KIND OF UNILATERAL
DECISION ABOUT OUR MARRIAGE?
HOW ABOUT THE FACT THAT YOU
MOVED ACROSS THE COUNTRY
AND DIDN'T HAVE THE COURAGE
TO DO WHAT I DID
AND SIMPLY ASK
FOR A DIVORCE?
(laughs) OH, GOD.
SO THIS IS BALLSY,
YOU HIDING BEHIND
THE LAWSUIT?
YOU COULDN'T JUST
ADMIT TO ME,
OR--OR--OR GOD SAKE, YOURSELF,
THAT YOU WANTED OUT.
YOU HAVE TO LET
THIS STUPID PLANE CRASH
MAKE THE DECISION FOR YOU.
I CHOSE THE AIRLINE!
YOU LIKE IT BETTER
WHEN I DECIDE?!
I CHOSE THE AIRLINE!
(sighs)
WE HAD TO MAKE A BUDGET CUT
OF 4%...
AND WE HAD A LINE ITEM
OF EMERGENCY TRANSPORTATION.
WE NEVER USED IT,
AND WE HAD A...
FANCY CHARTER COMPANY,
AND I CHOSE
A... CHEAPER ONE.
YOU WANT TO KNOW WHY
IT WAS CHEAPER?
YOU DIDN'T BUILD THE PLANE.
PEOPLE ARE DEAD.
OR FLY IT.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE DEAD.
YOU'RE NOT RESPONSIBLE.
(exhales)
SOMEONE HAS TO BE.
I MEAN, IT TAKES
A LOT OF SMALL MISTAKES
TO DESTROY SOMETHING,
AND IT'S REALLY EASY
FOR EVERYBODY INVOLVED
JUST TO SAY, "AH, I JUST DID
THIS ONE SMALL THING."
A BUNCH OF PEOPLE
MADE IT POSSIBLE...
FOR A BAD PLANE
TO TAKE OFF
WITH YOU, MEREDITH, AND DEREK,
AND ARIZONA, AND...
AND I AM
ONE OF THOSE PEOPLE.
(door closes)
GIVES YOU 1% CASH BACK
ON ALL PURCHASES,
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS.
AND EVERYONE...BUT HER
LIKES 50% MORE CASH.
BUT I'M UPPING MY GAME.
DO YOU WANT A CANDY CANE?
YES!
DO YOU WANT THE PUPPY?
DO YOU WANT A TRICYCLE?
YES!
DO YOU WANT
50 PERCENT MORE CASH?
NO!
♪
FESTIVE.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE Capital One
Cash Rewards Card
GIVES YOU
1% CASH BACK
ON EVERY
PURCHASE
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS
ON THE CASH YOU EARN.
IT'S THE CARD FOR PEOPLE
WHO LIKE MORE CASH.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
YOU WON'T TAKE OUR FUTURE.
AIDS AFFECTS US ALL.
EVEN BABIES.
CHEVRON IS WORKING TO STOP
MOTHER-TO-CHILD TRANSMISSION.
OUR EMPLOYEES AND THEIR FAMILIES
ARE PART OF THE FIGHT.
AND WE'RE WINNING.
AT CHEVRON NIGERIA, WE HAVEN'T
HAD A REPORTED CASE IN 12 YEARS.
AIDS IS STRONG.
BUT WE ARE STRONGER.
AND AIDS...
♪
AIDS IS GOING TO LOSE.
THAT'S WHY NEW
Dove Style + Care
Whipped Cream Mousse
NOURISHES AND CONDITIONS
TO HELP KEEP CURLS WELL DEFINED
AND TOUCHABLY SOFT.
NEW Dove Style + Care
Whipped Cream Mousse.
BETTER STYLE
THROUGH BETTER CARE.
I'VE GOT TO GET BREAKFAST READY
FOR MY TWO LEADING LADIES.
WHILE MANAGING THEIR SCHEDULE
WITH MY PRODUCING PARTNER.
I SET UP KID'S CORNER
SO THEY CAN LEARN AND PLAY GAMES
WITHOUT DELETING MY STUFF.
"WORKING MOM" IS SOMETIMES
A TOUGH ROLE TO PLAY,
BUT IT'S DEFINITELY
THE ONE I WAS BORN FOR.
[ clattering,
children laughing ]
AND...ACTION.
THAT'S ME.
AND THIS IS MY WINDOWS PHONE.
[ Male Announcer ]
NEW WINDOWS PHONE.
REINVENTED AROUND YOU.
♪
We can help people get termws.
life insurance for as low
as $14 a month.
LUCY:
I think it should be 5 cents.
CHARLIE:
Yeah, it should be five cents.
EMPLOYEE: Everything
can't be five cents.
ANNCR: Call 1-888-MetLife
to buy or apply today.
(Sky Ferreira's
"Lost In My Bedroom" playing)
♪ YOU'RE CRYSTAL CLEAR
♪ FACING THE LIGHT
♪ DON'T DISAPPEAR
♪ IT'S JUST WHAT I IMAGINED
♪ SO HAPPY HERE
♪ EVERYTHING'S FINE
♪ IT'S CRYSTAL CLEAR
(bracelets rattle)
♪ IT'S JUST WHAT I
♪ LOST IN MY BED
♪ AND I'M LOST IN MY HEAD
♪ AND I'M LOST
IN MY BEDROOM AGAIN ♪
♪ IT'S JUST WHAT I IMAGINED
♪ I'M LOST IN MY BEDROOM
♪ IT'S JUST WHAT IMAGINED
(sighs)
♪ IT'S JUST WHAT I IMAGINED
♪ I'M LOST IN MY BEDROOM
(monitor beeping rhythmically)
OH.
I THINK I'M HAVING A DREAM
A REALLY HOT DOCTOR
CAME TO TAKE CARE OF ME.
THIS REALLY HOT DOCTOR IS
LEAVING YOU TO GO TO A PARTY.
MM.
CALLIE SAID
IT COULD NOT HAVE GONE BETTER.
MM.
DO YOU HAVE ANY PAIN?
NO.
HOW'S LIZZIE?
UH, SHE'S DOING WELL.
SHE WAS STILL SLEEPING
LAST TIME I CHECKED.
I'LL SWING BY
ON MY WAY OUT.
(laughs)
MWAH. HEY.
IT MAY HAVE WORKED.
(sighs deeply)
AND WE'RE BACK ON THE SHOES.
PLEASE DON'T EVEN
SAY IT OUT LOUD.
IT MAKES ME FEEL
EVEN MORE STUPID.
JUST... (sighs) TELL HER
THAT I WASN'T FEELING WELL.
YOU'VE GOTTA BE KIDDING ME.
DO NOT BELITTLE ME, OKAY? YOU
HAVE NO IDEA WHAT IT'S LIKE--
OH, TRUST ME, TRUST ME,
I AM INTIMATELY FAMILIAR
WITH WHAT'S GOING ON,
AND I'M OVER IT.
YOU ARE EXACTLY THE SAME PERSON
YOU WERE BEFORE,
JUST MINUS A LEG.
YOU THINK IT'S NOTHING?
NO. OH, NO, NO, NO, NO.
I THINK IT'S EVERYTHING.
AND--AND YOU KNOW WHAT?
IT HAS BEEN... FOR MONTHS.
AND I HAVE BEEN SUPPORTIVE
FOR MONTHS.
BUT THERE COMES A POINT
WHERE YOU HAVE TO SUCK IT UP
AND STOP WHINING
AND START LIVING.
OKAY, SO YOU HAVE ONE LEG.
IT'S A WEDDING.
AND WEDDINGS ARE SWEET
AND BEAUTIFUL
AND N-NO ONE'S GONNA NOTICE
THE STUPID LEG
BECAUSE EVERYBODY'S GONNA
BE LOOKING AT BAILEY,
AND MAYBE FOR ONE NIGHT,
OUR LIVES CAN BE
ABOUT SOMETHING
OTHER THAN THAT DAMN LEG.
MY WHOLE LIFE
IS ABOUT THAT LEG.
I HAVEN'T HAD SEX IN FIVE MONTHS
BECAUSE OF THE LEG.
ENOUGH ABOUT THE LEG!
(car horn honks)
(exhales and groans)
EVERYTHING WENT SMOOTHLY.
YOUR VITALS LOOK GREAT.
AND DEREK IS AWAKE,
AND HE'S IN GOOD SHAPE.
MEREDITH, I'M PUSHY.
I GET THAT.
SOME PEOPLE FIND IT ENDEARING,
AND SOME PEOPLE REALLY DON'T,
BUT, UM...
YOU DON'T HAVE TO WANT
DEREK'S TRUCKLOAD OF SISTERS
IN YOUR LIFE.
(monitor beeping rhythmically)
YEAH. YOU ARE
A PAIN IN THE ASS.
AND I BARELY KNOW YOU.
(laughs)
(people speaking indistinctly)
OKAY, SO...
(chair wheels clatter)
I'M NOT VERY GOOD AT THIS.
BUT I'M GONNA TRY.
I'M GONNA SHOW YOU SOMETHING,
BUT YOU HAVE TO PROMISE NOT TO
BLAB IT TO THE WHOLE FAMILY.
OKAY.
PROMISE?
YEAH.
OKAY.
YOU?
REALLY?
WE'RE HAVING A BABY.
YEAH. (laughs)
YAY!
LET HER DRIVE YOU, MIRANDA.
NO, MOM.
I JUST NEED FIVE MINUTES
WITH NONE OF YOU TOUCHING ME.
(brakes squeak)
WH--
(Luke Sital-Singh's
"Fail For You" playing)
(sighs)
♪ THIS IS GETTING HARD TO BEAR
♪ FACE IT
I'M NOT GETTING THROUGH ♪
(Alex sighs)
SO DID SHE BRING HER FRIEND
OR WHAT?
(door opens)
♪ I DON'T EVEN THINK YOU CARE
OH, COME ON.
HE'S THE GUY?
♪ ALL THE THINGS
I'VE WON FOR YOU ♪
MM.
ALL RIGHT.
♪ ...YOUR CHAMPION
♪ SO WHY
♪ DO YOU WALK AWAY?
WAS THE LAWSUIT THE ONLY REASON
YOU ASKED FOR A DIVORCE?
♪ I
(sighs)
THERE ARE MANY REASONS.
(mutters) YOU WERE...
DONE
A LONG TIME AGO.
I'M ASKING ABOUT YOU.
♪ BY
♪ THE LOOK IN YOUR EYE
OKAY, LET ME PUT IT
ANOTHER WAY.
♪ THE ONLY THING
I COULDN'T DO ♪
I WANTED TO--TO TRY AGAIN.
♪ DON'T ASK ME
TO FAIL FOR YOU ♪
I WAS GONNA ASK YOU
IF WE COULD TRY AGAIN,
AND YOU SAID,
"I WANT A DIVORCE."
♪ OOH
♪ I
♪ FAIL FOR YOU ♪
♪ FAIL FOR YOU
COME HERE.
♪ ...FOR YOU
♪ FAIL FOR YOU
MM.
(cell phone rings)
OH. SORRY.
I SHOULD THROW THIS THING
OUT THE WINDOW.
(rings and beeps)
(laughs)
HELLO.
(man) Sir, this is Barrett
in the E.R.
Your wife is on her way here.
Paramedics say
she's vomiting blood.
WHAT?
ADELE?
She's hypotensive.
UM, HEY, UH,
TURN THE CAR AROUND.
WE NEED TO GO
TO THE EMERGENCY ROOM...
DID YOU CHECK HER VITALS?
AT SEATTLE GRACE HOSPITAL
RIGHT NOW.
(speaks indistinctly)
(tires squeal)
♪
(indistinct conversations)
WASN'T THIS STUPID THING
SUPPOSED TO START ALREADY?
(groans and coughs)
I'M--I'M--I'M HERE,
SWEETHEART.
(crying)
WHY IS THIS HAPPENING?
WE'RE GONNA FIND OUT.
HOW MUCH BLOOD HAS SHE LOST?
AT LEAST A LITER,
A LITER AND A HALF.
IT STARTED
ABOUT 45 MINUTES AGO.
OH, GOD! IT HURTS.
HANG MORE L.R.
NO, NOT IF SHE'S LOST
THAT MUCH BLOOD.
SHE NEEDS A TRANSFUSION
AND AN N.G. TUBE.
I'VE GOT THIS, OKAY?
SIR, SHE'S YOUR WIFE.
STEP BACK.
GET ME AN N.G. TUBE, SON.
I CAN DO THIS.
GET ME AN N.G. TUBE
RIGHT NOW.
OKAY, I GOT IT.
YOU HEAR ME?
(Adele panting)
OH.
(groans)
OKAY.
GET OUT OF THE WAY.
(moans)
OKAY. CENTRAL LINE KIT, PLEASE.
(woman) YES, DOCTOR.
YEAH, YEAH, LEAH.
GET ME OUT OF THIS DRESS NOW.
ADELE, HI.
CAN YOU LOOK AT ME?
HEY, WE'RE GONNA TAKE
GOOD CARE OF YOU, OKAY?
(monitor beeping rapidly)
SHE'S HAVING
VENTRICULAR COUPLETS.
ALL RIGHT, WATCH FOR V-TACH.
PREP THE I.J.
OKAY, YOU'RE GONNA
BE FINE, BABY. WE GOT YOU.
ALL RIGHT.
GET THE GUIDE WIRE READY.
(monitor beeping erratically)
SHE'S LOSING CONSCIOUSNESS.
BAILEY!
DAMN IT. ALL RIGHT.
UH, BARRETT, TAKE THIS.
DO A FEMORAL LINE INSTEAD.
UH, LEAH,
INTUBATION TRAY.
(beeping continues)
OH, GOD, ADELE.
OH, GOD.
(beeping continues)
(indistinct conversations)
OH, COME ON, COME ON,
COME ON.
OH, STRAIGHT TO VOICE MAIL.
(beeps)
(man) ♪ I STILL NEED
(sighs)
♪
(lowered voice) UM,
IT'S POSSIBLE
THAT I MAY HAVE, BY MISTAKE,
SAID THAT IF SHE HAD ANY DOUBTS,
SHE SHOULD FLEE.
WHAT?
WHY?
WELL, I KIND OF SAID
THAT MARRIAGE IS LIKE
A DANCE OF DEATH
AND THAT
LEAVING HIM AT THE ALTAR
WOULD BE A PAINFUL
BUT EFFICIENT OUT.
OH, THAT'S NICE.
I WAS JOKING...
OHH.
AND SHE WAS NERVOUS,
OKAY?
AND SHE WASN'T SURE
IF IT WAS THE WEDDING
OR THE WHOLE THING.
THE MARRIAGE?
(whispers)
SHE WAS NERVOUS.
HOW NERVOUS?
♪ MORE THAN EVERYTHING
HOW NERVOUS WAS SHE, CALLIE?