NOW, YOU HAVE BEEN IN THAT
COMMUNITY FOR SEVERAL HOURS NOW,
THIS IS A TIGHT-KNIT COMMUNITY,
WE CAN ONLY IMAGINE THE FEAR FOR
THE FAMILIES THAT HAVE YET TO
REUNITE WITH THEIR CHILDREN.
>> THAT'S RIGHT, DAVID,
TIGHT-KNIT, WORKING-CLASS
COMMUNITY, YOU CAN'T IMAGINE
WHAT'S GOING THROUGH, YOU KNOW,
PEOPLE'S HEARTS AND THEIR MINDS.
I MEAN, EVEN IF YOU WEREN'T
DIRECTLY INVOLVED YOU'RE GOING
TO KNOW SOMEBODY WHO WAS, YOU'RE
GOING TO FEEL FOR SOMEONE WHO
WAS.
THIS IS GOING TO BE A VERY, VERY
PAINFUL PLACE FOR PEOPLE.
YES, THE SCENE OF THE HOSPITAL
IS ONE OF ABJECT GRIEF.
NURSES KRIELG IN HALLWAYS.
AND AS I SAID BEFORE, INKOLL
SABL AND HEARTBROKEN BECAUSE
THEY WEREN'T ABLE TO TREAT MORE
PEOPLE.
NOT ABLE TO DO MORE FOR THE
CHILDREN IN THAT SCHOOL, THE
FACULTY AND THE STAFF.
NO QUESTION ABOUT IT.
VERY, VERY PAINFUL, VERY
DIFFICULT PLACE TO BE.
WE'RE EXPECTING A NEWS
CONFERENCE HERE IN THE NEXT HOUR
OR SO.
HOPEFULLY, WE'LL HAVE DETAILS
AND MAYBE WE'LL HAVE SOME GOOD
NEWS, SOME GOOD NEWS TO BRING
YOU ABOUT THE CONDITIONS OF THE
THREE PEOPLE WHO WERE BROUGHT
HERE TO THE HOSPITAL.
>> IT WOULD BE WELCOMED ON AN
AFTERNOON THAT THIS IS PLAYING
OUT IN FRONT OF AMERICA.
IT'S 2:02.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A QUICK
BREAK AND RESET FOR THE COUNTRY.
FOR MANY OF THE VIEWERS TUNING
IN, AROUND 9:30, THE FIRST CALLS
CAME IN.
THAT THERE HAD BEEN A SHOOTING
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
IT TAKES 45 MINUTES TO GET THERE
FROM NEW YORK.
WE'RE TOLD AT THIS HOUR THAT
THERE ARE AT LEAST 27 DEAD.
THE SHOOTER BELIEVED TO BE
CARRYING FOUR WEAPONS.
24 YEARS OLD.
WAS WEARING A BULLETPROOF VEST
ENTERED THE SCHOOL AND BEGAN
FIRING.
THAT SHOOTER IS DECEASED.
WE DON'T KNOW IF THERE WAS MORE
THAN ONE SHOOTER INVOLVED.
WE CERTAINLY DON'T KNOW TOO
EARLY TO SAY WHAT COULD HAVE
BEEN THE MOTIVE FOR SUCH A
HEINOUS CRIME AND TO PUT THIS
INTO PERSPECTIVE, WHAT YOU'RE
WATCHING UNFOLD TODAY WILL BE
THE DEADLIEST SHOOTING AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN AMERICA
HISTORY, THE SECOND DEADLIEST
SHOOTING BEHIND VIRGINIA TECH,
AS YOU REMEMBER, WE ALL FOLLOWED
THAT CLOSELY.
MORE THAN A DOZEN SHOT AND
KILLED IN COLUMBINE.
BUT TODAY, THE NUMBERS ARE
SIMPLY STAGGERING.
AT LEAST 27 SHOT AND KILLED.
AND MANY OF THE VICTIMS ARE
CHILDREN.
I WAS STRUCK BY THE DESCRIPTION
EARLIER, SIMPLY REMINDING US OF
WHAT WE ALL KNOW AS WE TAKE THE
KIDS TO SCHOOL, SCHOOLS ARE
OFTEN MADE UP LONG HALLWAYS WITH
CLASSROOM DOORS.
UNFORTUNATELY, THAT'S THE
ENTRANCE TO THE CLASSROOM.
IF YOU HAVE A SUSPECT THAT
APPROACHES THAT CLASSROOM DOOR
AS PERHAPS WAS THE CASE TODAY
THERE IS JUST VERY LITTLE OTHER
THAN ASKING THE CHILDREN TO
PERHAPS DIVE UNDER THEIR DESKS.
WE DO KNOW THAT PARENTS TELLING
US EARLIER IN OUR LIVE COVERAGE
OF THIS INCIDENT THAT THE
TEACHERS WERE EXTRAORDINARILY
CALM IN TAKING THESE CHILDREN
OUT OF THE SCHOOL.
KIDS WERE TOLD TO COVER THEIR
EYES.
THEY WERE ALSO TOLD TO GRAB A
FRIEND AND LEAVE ALL OF YOUR
BELONGINGS BEHIND.
LOOK AT THIS.
THEIR FACES SAY IT ALL.
AND IF YOU NOTICED WHICH I
CERTAINLY DID EARLY, NONE OF
THEM HAVE THEIR COATS ON AS THEY
WALK OUT OF THAT SCHOOL AND LOOK
AT THOSE ADULTS IN THAT FRAME,
INTENT ON GETTING THOSE CHILDREN
TO THAT NEIGHBORING FIRE HOUSE
THERE IN SANDY HOOK.
THERE'S A VOLUNTEER FIRE HOUSE
JUST ADJACENT TO THAT SCHOOL AND
THAT IS WHERE TEACHERS WERE TOLD
TO TAKE THE CHILDREN JUST AS
SOON AS THEY COULD AND PERHAPS
IN A SIGN OF THE TIMES, LOT OF
THESE PARENTS GOT A REVERSE TEXT
ALERT ON THEIR CELL PHONES, AND
INITIALLY IT DIDN'T EVEN SAY THE
NAME OF THE SCHOOL IS WHAT MY
UNDERSTANDING IS FROM THE
REPORTING HERE TODAY.
SO, YOU COULD ONLY IMAGINE AS
PARENTS WAITING TO HEAR IF IT
WAS THEIR SCHOOL.
THEY RECEIVED A REVERSE 911
TEXT.
TECHNOLOGY THAT ALERTS US IF OUR
CHILDREN ARE IN DANGER NOW IN
AMERICA.
THEY WERE TOLD TO GO TO THAT
FIRE HOUSE.
>>> SECURITY AT SCHOOLS IN
AMERICA, AS YOU KNOW, IT'S
ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE TO LOCK UP
THESE ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS IN
AMERICA OR MIDDLE SCHOOLS OR
HIGH SCHOOLS, IT WOULD SIMPLY BE
OVERWHELMING TO DO.
I KNOW FROM MY OWN EXPERIENCE,
AS YOU WALK INTO THE FRONT DOOR,
THEY'LL GUIDE YOU TO THE OFFICE,
YOU HAVE TO SIGN IN AND MANY
SCHOOLS HAVE A PASS AND THERE
ARE HALL MONITORS, SOMETIMES
SECURITY TO MAKE SURE THERE'S NO
ONE SUSPICIOUS TO ENTER SCHOOL.
TO HAVE A SCHOOL IN LOCKDOWN
AFTER INCIDENTS LIKE THIS IS
ALMOST AN UNATTAINABLE GOAL TO
HAVE AND NOT ONE THAT WE HAVE IN
AMERICA.
I'M JUST GETTING WORD FROM ONE
OF OUR OTHER AFFILIATES WTNH,
SPEAKING TO A 17-YEAR-OLD, HE
HAS A FOURTH GRADER IN THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, THEY HAVE
BEEN REUNITED.
I WANTED TO TAKE A LISTEN HERE
AND WE'LL TALK HERE ON THE
BACKSIDE.
>> MY WHOLE LIFE WAS MY SISTER
WAS JUST REPLAYING THROUGH MY
HEAD.
I WAS SAYING TO MYSELF, I'M
SORRY TO WHATEVER I DID.
IT WAS VERY TRAUMATIZINTRAUMATI.
TRUTHFULLY, I HAD TO BE CALMED
BY OTHER PEOPLE.
OTHER PEOPLE WERE COMING UP TO
ME, THEY WERE HUGGING ME.
MY MOM WAS CRYING HER EYES OUT.
>> NUMBERS OF STUDENTS HAVE LOST
THEIR LIVES, WHAT DO YOU THINK
ABOUT THIS, THIS IS HAPPENING
QUITE A BIT LATELY?
>> IT'S A GROWING TREND.
I FEEL LIKE, YOU KNOW, I FEEL
LIKE THERE ARE CERTAIN LEN
YENSIES IN TERMS OF LAWYERS
PERMITTING THIS TO HAPPEN.
>> WE TALKED TO A PARENT
EARLIER, WHEN YOU AND YOUR MOM
GO TO THE SCHOOL TO PICK UP YOUR
SISTER ANY GIVEN DAY, IS IT EASY
TO GET IN AND OUT OF THE SCHOOL,
DO THEY CHECK YOUR I.D.?
>> THEY DON'T CHECK I.D.
AGAIN, THERE ARE REGULATIONS AND
YOU KNOW, I'M NOT SURE IF THAT'S
A FAIR COMPARISON, THIS GUY CAME
IN WITH A GUN, IT'S NOT
COMPARABLE TO SAY, THIS CHILDREN
LEFT THE SCHOOL.
A GUY COMING WITH A GUN IS
TOTALLY DIFFERENT.
>> SOMETHING THAT'S COMPLETELY
UNEXPECTED FOR THIS AREA.
>> LITERALLY THE WORST CRIME WE
HAVE HERE IS, WE DON'T HAVE EVEN
CRIME.
THE WORST I HAVE HEARD HERE IS
SOME THEFTS OF CARS.
>> YOU'RE HERE RIGHT NOW BECAUSE
YOU WANT ANSWERS.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
I WAS ONE OF THE FIRST ONES
THERE.
IT'S TRULY DISGUSTING WHAT'S
HAPPENING.
>> TRULY DISGUSTING WHAT'S
THAT FROM A 17-YEAR-OLD BOY WHO
WAS REUNITED WITH HIS LITTLE
SISTER IN THE FOURTH GRADER.
ONE OF THE MANY CHILDREN.
500 CHILDREN BELIEVED GO TO THIS
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
CLUTCHING ONE ANOTHER, AS THEIR
TEACHERS BROUGHT THEM TO SAFETY
AT THE FIRE HOUSE.
WTNH JOINING US COVERAGE.
>>> I WANT TO BRING IN DR.
RICHARD BESSER, THE CHILDREN
LEAVING THE SCHOOL, THERE WERE
REPORTS OF CRIES AND TEARS BUT
NO OVERDICT SCREAMING, THEY WERE
VERY CALM AND IT WAS THE
17-YEAR-OLD A MOMENT AGO WHO
SAID THAT HE HAD TO BE CALMED
DOWN BY PEOPLE ON THE SCENE THAT
HIS MOTHER HAD TO BE CALMED
DOWN, IT'S THE ADULTS IN THIS
SITUATION, THE OLDER STUDENTS
WHO KNOW THE SCOPE OF THIS IS
GOING TO BE EXTRAORDINARY TO
HELP THEM DEAL IT WITH FIRST TO
THEN HELP THE YOUNGER MEMBERS OF
THEIR FAMILIES WHO SURVIVED THIS
ORDEAL.
>> DAVID, I THINK YOU'RE RIGHT
ON TRACK.
HOW PEOPLE REACT TO THIS WILL
DEPEND ON A LOT ON THEIR AGE,
THEIR LEVEL OF DEVELOPMENT AND
HOW MUCH THEY'RE EXPOSED TO
THIS.
VERY YOUNG CHILDREN, MAY NOT BE
ABLE TO COMPREHEND THIS,
CHILDREN UNDER 7, TO USE A
CUTOFF, DON'T LET THEM HEAR THE
REPORTS.
TRY NOT LET THEM SEE THE
COVERAGE OF THIS ON TELL VIX.
THAT REPEATED EXPOSURE CAN BE
QUITE TRAUMATIC.
YOU HAVE TO LOOK AT THE AGE OF
THE CHILD AND DEAL WITH THEM.
KNOWING YOUR CAN CLIELD IS VERY,
VERY IMPORTANT.
>> KNOWING YOUR CHILD IS VERY,
I'M NOT SURE RICH IS STILL WITH
US.
>> WHEN YOU LOOK AT THOSE
CHILDREN WHO ARE SCHOOL AGED, 7
TO TEENAGED YEARS, THEY'LL BE
LOOKING TO SEE HOW YOU RESPOND
TO THIS.
ARE YOU ABLE TO EXPRESS YOUR
ANGRY AND YOUR SADNESS OVER T  S
THIS.
THAT'S VERY IMPORTANT.
ASKING THEM HOW THEY'RE FEELING
IS VERY IMPORTANT.
BUT GIVING THEM THE OVERALL
SENSE THAT THIS IS A VERY BAD
THING THAT HAPPENED, YOUR JOB AS
A PARENT IS TO KEEP THEM SAFE
AND THAT THEY'RE SAFE.
THE TEENAGERS, YOU WANT TO
ENGAGE IN A CONVERSATION, YOU
WANT TO GET A SENSE OF WHY THEY
THINK THIS HAPPENED.
AND TRY TO THEM ENGAGE IN A
CONVERSATION, SO THEY CAN BEGIN
TO PROCESS THIS.
>> TO REASSURE THEM.
ONE OF THE THINGS THAT WE HAVE
CONTINUED TO POINT OUT THIS
MORNING, TUNING INTO OUR
BREAKING NEWS COVERAGE ON THIS
HORRIFIC SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, IF YOU HAVE
CHILDREN IN THE ROOM, THIS IS
CERTAINLY NOT SOMETHING THEY
NEED TO CARRY ON THEIR YOUNG
SHOULDERS AS WE LEARN MORE AND
MORE ABOUT WHAT PLAYED OUT HERE
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
I WANT TO BRING IN FORMER FBI
PROFILER BRAD GARRETT.
BRAD, WE BRING YOU IN WHEN
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS PLAY OUT.
RIGHT NOW AS IT STANDS, STATE
POLICE CONFIRMING THAT THE
SHOOTER WENT INSIDE, BELIEVED TO
HAVE HAD FOUR WEAPONS, HAD A
VEST ON, ONE MOTHER SAID A MASK,
AND AS ALWAYS THE CASE, WE ASK
OURSELVES, WHAT ON EARTH WOULD
LEAD SOMEONE TO DO SOMETHING
LIKE THIS?
>> TO THE CLIFF, I HAVE LOST
POWER, IT COULD BE SOMETHING
THAT HE HAD A CHILD IN THE
SCHOOL, HE HAD A DOMESTIC
DISPUTE.
DRIVEN THIS PERSON RIGHT UP TO I
HAVE LOST COMPLETE CONTROL OF MY
LIFE AND I DON'T CARE ANYMORE.
AS DIFFICULT FOR PEOPLE TO
UNDERSTAND THIS, THIS IS HOW
THEY EMPOWER THEMSELVES, WHETHER
IT BE A FEW DAYS AGO IN
PORTLAND, OREGON, OR AURORA,
COLORADO, THEY PUT ON AN OUTFIT,
I'M GOING TO CALL IT A COSTUME,
BECAUSE THEY'RE PLAYING A
DIFFERENT CHARACTER, THEY'RE
GOING IN THERE AND THEY DON'T
VIEW THESE CHILDREN OR THE
ADULTS AS HUMAN BEINGS, THEY
VIEW THEM AS THE ENEMY, AS
PEOPLE WHO HAVE WRONGED THEM FOR
WHATEVER REASON AND THEY'RE
GOING TO SEEK REVENGE.
UNFORTUNATELY, THIS GUY CREATED
TREMENDOUS, TREMENDOUS TRAGEDY.
>> BUT HOW COULD SOMEONE LOOK AT
CHILDREN, INNOCENT CHILDREN OF
THIS AGE AS BEING THE ENEMY?
>> BECAUSE, THEY DON'T LOOK AT
IT AS A CHILD.
THEY LOOK AT IT AS THEY CAN TAKE
CONTROL OF THE SITUATION, AND
THEY CAN START KILLING PEOPLE
AND THAT'S ALL THEY THINK ABOUT.
I UNDERSTAND WHAT YOU'RE SAYING.
ONE THING TO SHOOT 30-YEAR-OLD
DOCUMENT, IT'S ANOTHER THING TO
SHOOT A 7-YEAR-OLD.
BUT THEY DON'T CARE.
THEY HAVE COMPLETELY LOST THEIR
TOUCH, THEIR EMPATHY, THEIR
CARING FOR ANYONE.
IT'S ALL ABOUT ME, IT'S ALL
ABOUT ME GETTING MY FEELINGS
OUT.
THAT'S REALLY WHAT'S GONE ON
WITH THESE SHOOTERS.
YOU GOT SOMEBODY OLDER, MOST
SCHOOLTEACHERS TEND TO BE
STUDENTS THAT GO BACK, BUT THIS
WAS AN OLDER PERSON, WAS HE
WRONGED BY THE SCHOOL?
ONE THING THAT THE INVESTIGATORS
WILL LOOK AT, IS THERE A BIGGER
AGENDA HERE?
>> BRAD, AS ALWAYS THE CASE, YOU
HELP US WRAP OUR HEADS AROUND
SOMETHING THAT'S SIMPLY
UNFATHOMAB
UNFATHOMABLE.
THIS IS THE SCHOOL SHOOTING THAT
BEGAN THIS MORNING WITH A CALL
SHORTLY AFTER 9:30.
THE FEAR WAS, THAT THIS WAS
GOING TO BE SOMETHING BIG.
HISTORIC IN FACT IN NATURE.
THE WORST SHOOTING AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN THIS
COUNTRY, EVER, AT LEAST 27 SHOT
AND KILLED.
WE BELIEVE MANY OF THEM ARE
CHILDREN, THE SHOOTER, AT LEAST
ONE SHOOTER, THE SHOOTER INSIDE
THE BUILDING CONFIRMED IS DEAD.
BRAD TRIED TO DESCRIBE WHAT
COULD HAPPEN IN SOMEONE'S LIFE
THAT LEAD THEM TO COMMITTING
SUCH A HEINOUS ACT.
I WANT TO BRING IN N.J. BURKETT.
WE JUST GOT WORD OF THE SCHOOL
SECURITY POLICY.
A LETTER WENT OUT TO ALL PARENTS
IN THAT SCHOOL DISTRICT.
NOT LONG AGO, IN FACT, THEY
UPDATED THEIR SECURITY POLICY.
THIS ISN'T GOING TO SOUND UNLIKE
ANY OTHER SECURITY, EVERY
VISITOR WILL RING THE BELL.
VISITORS WILL BE REQUIRED TO
REPORT TO THE OFFICE AND SIGNED
IN.
WHICH WE PRESUMED WAS THE CASE.
SO OFTEN THE PROCEDURE IN
SCHOOLS ACROSS THE COUNTRY RIGHT
NOW.
AS THAT 17-YEAR-OLD PUT IT
MOMENTS AGO, THIS MAN WAS ARMED,
IT MAKES IT ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE TO
FOLLOW PROCEDURE, BUT WHAT'S
GOING TO BE FRIGHTENING FOR
THESE PARENTS, THE RULES HAD
BEEN FOLLOWED AND FOR SOME TIME
NOW AT THIS SCHOOL.
>> WELL, THAT'S RIGHT, DAVID.
YOU HAVE TO IMAGINE WHAT THEIR
REACTION IS GOING TO BE AS THIS
WHOLE STORY UNFOLDS AS FACTS
COME OUT.
SEVERAL HOURS LATER, WE'RE
STARTING TO LEARN ABOUT WHAT
POLICIES WERE IN PLACE.
WHAT POLICIES MAY HAVE BEEN
FOLLOWED.
IN A LOT OF URBAN SCHOOLS IN
AMERICA, A LOT OF URBAN SCHOOLS
IN AMERICA, THERE ARE METAL
DETECTORS, BUT IN A PLACE LIKE
THIS, YOU DON'T SEE THOSE METAL
DETECTORS.
YOU DON'T SEE THOSE KIND OF
SECURITY MEASURES, LOT OF THE
SECURITY MEASURES GO BACK TO
THAT HORRIFIC SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
DUNBLANE, SCOTLAND, THAT
TRAUMATIZED PEOPLE THERE AND
THIS WOULD BE APPEAR TO BE FROM
WHAT WE'RE HEARING AND SEEING,
DUNBLANE TIMES TWO.
IT'S ABSOLUTELY HORRIFIC.
I DESCRIBED THE SCENE INSIDE THE
HOSPITAL, DANBURY HOSPITAL,
WHERE THREE OF THE VICTIMS WERE
TAKEN.
WE HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE TO CONFIRM
THE CONDITIONS OF THOSE VICTIMS.
WE'RE HOPING TO KNOW MORE
SHORTLY.
BUT, THE SCENE INSIDE THE
HOSPITAL IS JUST ONE OF AS I
DESCRIBED IT AS ABJECT GRIEF,
NURSES CRYING IN THE HALLWAYS,
PEOPLE, EVEN PATIENTS HERE
INCOLOSABLE TRYING TO WRAP THEIR
MINDS AROUND THIS.
HOW EVIL DO YOU HAVE TO BE TO DO
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
>> THAT IN FACT IS THE BIG
QUESTION.
WE'LL HAVE DAIS TO FIGURE THAT
OUT.
N.J., ONE THING THAT STOPPED US
IN OUR TRACKS, YOU'RE AT DANBURY
HOSPITAL, THAT WAS THE
DESIGNATED TRIAGE CENTER FOR
THIS TRAGEDY AS IT UNFOLDED
TODAY BUT WHAT'S DIFFERENT ABOUT
THE TRAGEDY TODAY SO OFTEN, YOU
SEE THE GURNEYS BEING RUSHED IN
WITH THE INJURED, THE NUMBER
THAT YOU OFFERED, ONLY THREE
MADE IT TO THE HOSPITAL WOULD
SAY PERHAPS A LOT OF WHAT
UNFOLDED AT THAT SCHOOL.
>> WELL, WITHOUT QUESTION.
AND YOU KNOW, THE PEOPLE HERE,
THE DOCTORS, THE NURSES, THE
STAFF WERE HOPING THEY WOULD BE
ABLE TO TREAT MORE PEOPLE, THEY
ONLY GOT TO TREAT THREE PEOPLE
AND ALTHOUGH IT'S A DIFFERENT
SCALE, IT'S A DIFFERENT
SITUATION, BUT IT WAS
REMINISCENT TO US THAT COVERED
9/11 OF THE SCENES OUTSIDE
HOSPITALS IN NEW YORK CITY WHERE
THE DOCTORS AND THE NURSES WERE
WAITING FOR PATIENTS WHO NEVER
CAME.
AND THAT'S WHAT WE'RE SEEING
HERE.
>> N.J., I KNOW THAT YOU'RE
REPORTING 24 HOURS NOW FOR
CHANNEL 7 HERE IN NEW YORK.
WE APPRECIATE YOU TAKING TIME TO
TALK WITH US.
FOR THOSE OF YOU WHO ARE
WATCHING FROM OTHER PARTS OF THE
COUNTRY, AN IDEA OF WHERE THIS
SCHOOL IS, IT'S NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, 60 MILES NORTHEAST
OF NEW YORK CITY, A 45-MINUTE
DRIVE OR AN HOUR AT THE MOST IF
TRAFFIC IS GOOD.
AS WE PULL OUT, YOU CAN SEE THE
TOWN.
THAT'S THE HOSPITAL WHERE N.J.
WAS REPORTING JUST MOMENTS AGO.
NOT FAR FROM THE SCHOOL.
WHEN THE INITIAL CALL WENT OUT,
THEY THOUGHT THEY WOULD BE
TREATING A LOT OF INJURIES.
SO FAR, ONLY THREE PEOPLE HAVE
BEEN BROUGHT TO THE HOSPITAL AND
WHILE YOU DON'T WANT ANYONE END
UP IN THE HOSPITAL, THE HOPE AS
THIS BEGAN UNFOLD, THE HOPE THAT
MANY MADE IT TO THE HOSPITAL.
THE NUMBER IS SIMPLY STAGGERING.
AT LEAST 27 DEAD.
THAT'S THE LATEST NUMBER THAT WE
HAVE.
WE KNOW MANY OF THEM ARE
CHILDREN.
WE KNOW PARENTS ARE ON THE
SCENE.
MOST OF THE PARENTS WHOSE
CHILDREN MADE IT OUT HAVE
ALREADY BEEN REUNITED.
YOU CAN SEE AN ADULT WITH THREE
CHILDREN WALKING OUT THERE.
CHILDREN HOLDING HANDS.
DOING WHAT THEY WERE TOLD AND
DOING WHAT THEY WERE SUPPOSED TO
DO AT THE TIME OF THE MORNING.
SCHOOL WAS UNDER WAY.
IN THAT SMALL, PICTURESQUE TOWN.
THEN THEY SAW THIS, AUTHORITIES
WITH GUNS DRAWN AS THEY WENT CAR
TO CAR LOOKING FOR EVIDENCE.
INITIALLY LOOKING FOR ANYBODY
ELSE WHO WHITE HAVE BEEN
INVOLVED.
THIS IS THE SCENE.
AMBULANCES THERE.
AND THEY WERE HOPING TO BE ABLE
TO HELP MORE PEOPLE.
BUT AS WE KNOW NOW, THERE ARE
MANY VICTIMS INSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
AND IT'S BELIEVED THOSE VICTIMS
INCLUDE STAFF AND STUDENTS.
PERHAPS SOME TEACHERS WHO WERE
IN THEIR CLASSROOMS.
AS WE DESCRIBED THE LAYOUT.
ON A FRIDAY MORNING, IN THEIR
CLASSROOM, USUALLY JUST ONE DOOR
IN, AND IF THAT GUNMAN, THAT
SUSPECT APPROACHED THAT DOOR,
THERE IS NOT A LOT THAT A
TEACHER CAN DO ALTHOUGH TEACHERS
IN THIS SCHOOL TODAY WHO WERE
ABLE TO DO SOMETHING ACTED WITH
BRAVERY AND WITH COURAGE AS YOU
WATCH THEM WALK OUT AND YOU
COULD SEE IT ON THEIR FACES EVEN
IN THE STILL IMAGES, CHILDREN
WITHOUT THEIR COATS.
THERE'S A FIRE HOUSE AROUND THE
CORNER.
AND THAT'S WHERE THEY BROUGHT
THE CHILDREN.
CAN YOU IMAGINE THE TASK OF
GETTING 500 CHILDREN OUT OF THE
SCHOOL?
NOT KNOWING IF THE INCIDENT HAD
ENDED AND IF THE SCENE WAS
SECURED?
I WANT TO BRING IN PIERRE
THOMAS, OUR SENIOR JOS
CORRESPONDENT.
PIERRE, WE KNOW THAT VERY EARLY
ON, THE PRESIDENT WAS NOTIFIED.
JAKE TAPPER IS IN THE BRIEFING
ROOM.
BUT IN THE MEANTIME, TAKE US
THROUGH HOW THE PRESIDENT IS
BRIEFED, HOW QUICKLY THIS
INFORMATION IS GETTING TO HIM
AND WE KNOW THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT NOW BRIEFING THE
PARENTS.
>> THE WAY THIS UNFOLDED THE
FBI, YOU KNOW, THEY HAVE LOCAL
OFFICES THROUGHOUT THE COUNTRY,
THE LOCAL FBI OFFICE WAS
NOTIFIED ABOUT THE SHOOTING,
THEY SENT PERSONNEL TO THE
SCENE, THEN THAT INFORMATION
MADE ITS WAY TO THE FBI
DIRECTOR.
THE FBI DIRECTOR THAN INFORMED
THE PRESIDENT OF THE SCALE OF
THE EVENT AND HOW HORRIFIC IT
WAS AND THAT'S HOW WE UNDERSTAND
THIS WENT DOWN.
WE'RE ALSO GETTING SOME
ADDITIONAL INFORMATION ABOUT THE
SHOOTER IN THIS CASE.
WE ARE BEING TOLD THAT HE'S AN
IDENTIFIED AS A 24-YEAR-OLD.
WE'LL BE GATHERING MORE
INFORMATION TO GIVE TO OUR
VIEWERS AS WE GET MORE DETAIL.
>> PIERRE, I HAVE BEEN HANDED
SOME INFORMATION THAT'S BEEN
SENT OUT FOR OUR VIEWERS, WE
HAVE AN INTERNAL E-MAIL SYSTEM
THAT WE BRIEF EACH OTHER AND OUR
UNIT IS TELLING US THAT THIS WAS
A 24-YEAR-OLD MAN WHO OBVIOUSLY
FEDERAL AUTHORITIES ARE TRYING
TO INVESTIGATE, TO DETERMINE
WHETHER OR NOT HE WAS RELATED TO
SOME WAY TO SOMEONE IN THAT
SCHOOL.
>> I HAVE MULTIPLE SOURCES
TELLING ME THAT SAME
INFORMATION.
24-YEAR-OLD HAS EMERGED AS THE
LEADING SCHT AS THE PERSON THEY
BELIEVE DID THE SHOOTING.
HE'S THOUGHT TO HAVE HAD AN
RELATIONSHIP WITH SOMEONE AT THE
SCHOOL.
THIS IS VERY FLUID SITUATION.
THEY'RE DOING A SEARCH AT THE
MAN'S HOME.
WE HOPE TO HAVE SOME MORE
INFORMATION ABOUT THAT SHORTLY.
>>> BRAD GARRETT A FORMER FBI
PROFILER, HE'S AN ABC NEWS
ANALYST, HE'S COMING TO OUR
WASHINGTON BUREAU TODAY, HE WAS
TRYING TO HELP US FIGURE OUT
SOME REASONING WHY SOMEONE WOULD
DO THIS.
WE OFTEN POINT TO ILLNESS AFTER
CASES LIKE THIS.
I WAS STRUCK BY THE AGE, 24
YEARS OLD.
COLUMBINE, VIRGINIA TECH, THEY
WERE STUDENTS AT THOSE
PARTICULAR SCHOOLS INVOLVED.
BUT THIS WAS AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
WHEN YOU HEAR 24 YEARS OLD, YOU
IMMEDIATELY THINK, THIS IS A
LITTLE DIFFERENT FROM WHAT WE
HAVE SEEN.
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
DAVID, AS WE TALKED ABOUT
EARLIER, WHAT'S THE CONNECTION
BETWEEN THE SHOOTER WITH THE
SCHOOL?
IF THERE'S A CHILD, SHOOTER'S
CHILD, CONNECTED TO THE SHOOTER
SOME WAY, ONE QUICK SCENARIO, IF
THIS INVOLVES A DOMESTIC
SITUATION, HE LOST CUSTODY OF
THIS CHILDREN, IN MURDERS OF
CHILDREN BY THE FATHERS, IT'S
MAINLY DRIVEN MANY TIMES BY
WANTING TO KILL THE MOTHER AND
THE CHILDREN BECAUSE THEY
BELIEVE THE MOTHER PRODUCED THIS
CHILD AND NO ONE ELSE IS GOING
TO HAVE THIS CHILD I'M GOING TO
TAKE THIS CHILD OUT.
NOW, WHAT WOULD YOU DO THAT AND
KILL AOTHER CHILDREN?
THE REAL MOTIVE OF THIS, WE'RE
GOING TO LOOK AT THIS AND GO,
HOW IN THE WORLD COULD YOU KILN
ANYBODY BASED ON WHAT YOU'RE
TELLING ME?
BUT ONCE YOU REACH A POINT WHERE
NOTHING ELSE IS GOING TO RESOLVE
YOUR SITUATION, AND THE ANGER
AND RAGE ARE SO GREAT TOWARD
PERHAPS ANOTHER ADULT, PERHAPS
TOWARD A CHILD AT THE SCHOOL,
THEN YOU GO INTO THIS MODE
WHERE, AS I MENTIONED EARLIER,
YOU'RE NOT KILLING HUMAN BEINGS
YOU'RE JUST INFLICTING RAGE.
AND WITH THAT RAGE, YOU FEEL
MORE POWERFUL AT LEAST FOR THE
MOMENT AND THAT'S WHY SO MANY OF
THESE SHOOTERS THEY SHOOT
THEMSELVES OR POLICE SHOOT THEM
AT THE END OF THE RAM PAGE.
>> WE'RE WAITING TO HEAR ALL
THIS ENDED.
THE GUNMAN INSIDE THE SCHOOL IS
DEAD.
BELIEVED TO HAVE BEEN CARRYING
FOUR WEAPONS.
ONE MOTHER WE TALKED TO EARLIER
DESCRIBED THE GUNMAN INSIDE THE
BUILDING AS HAVING A MASK ON AS
THIS GUNMAN WENT THROUGH THE
BUILDING.
AND OBVIOUSLY, WE'LL ALSO BE
LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE PATH THE
GUNMAN TOOK TO HELP US DETERMINE
PERHAPS WHY THIS SCHOOL, WHY
THIS PARTICULARS CLASSROOM, I
WANT TO CHECK IN WITH DAN
HARRIS.
WHO'S BEEN THERE FOR HOURS ON
THE SCENE.
HE WAS AT THAT FIRE HOUSE WHERE
THOSE REUNIONS WERE TAKING
PLACE.
DAN, I CAN ONLY IMAGINE THE
SCENE BETWEEN THE GOVERNOR DAN
MALLOY THERE IN CONNECTICUT AND
THE PARENTS WAITING TO HEAR.
>> IT'S GOT TO BE A WRENCHING
JOB THAT THE GOVERNOR HAS IN
FRONT OF HIM RIGHT NOW.
WE HAVE SEEN HIM BRIEFLY, WE SAW
HIM LEAVING THE FIRE HOUSE AND
WE SAW HIM COMING BACK.
WE KNOW AS HIS SPOKESPERSON SAID
EARLIER, HE HAS BEEN SPEAKING
WITH THE PARENTS.
THAT'S WHAT'S TAKING PLACE RIGHT
NOW.
THIS IS THE VOLUNTEER FIRE HOUSE
RIGHT DOWN THIS STREET.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
RIGHT DOWN THIS STREET IS WHERE
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IS.
THE STUDENTS WERE RUSHED OUT OF
THE SCHOOL AND BROUGHT TO THIS
FIRE STATION.
PARENTS COMING HERE TO REUNITE
WITH THEIR CHILDREN.
ONE OF THE MOST POIGNANT THINGS
THAT WE HAVE SEEN TODAY, ONE OF
THE HORRIFYING THINGS, PARENTS,
MARRIED COUPLES LEAVING HERE ARM
IN ARM WITHOUT THEIR CHILDREN.
ONE CAN SIMPLY USE BASIC LOGIC
TO DEDUCE PERHAPS THEY LOST
THEIR CHILD.
THERE WILL BE MORE THAN 20
PARENTS WHO GET TERRIBLE,
TERRIBLE NEWS TODAY AS THIS
UNFOLDS.
AND THE GOVERNOR IS DOING SOME
OF THAT HARD WORK RIGHT NOW.
ONE PRESUMES.
THE OTHER THING THAT WE'RE
SEEING HERE TODAY AMBULANCES
LEAVING THE SCHOOL WITHOUT THEIR
LIGHTS ON, AS YOU DISCUSSED,
THEY WOULD MUCH RATHER TAKING
THE WOUNDED TO THE HOSPITAL
INSTEAD OF SIMPLY DEALING WITH
THE DEAD, WHICH IS WHAT IT
APPEARS THEY'RE DOING RIGHT NOW.
>> DAN, YOU'RE STANDING ABOUT AN
HOUR FROM THE STUDIO HERE IN NEW
YORK.
WE WERE STANDING OUT IN THE
HALL, DISCUSSING AS YOU WERE ON
THE WAY OUT, WE NEVER KNOW WHEN
WE LEAVE FOR THESE STORIES, HOW
IT WILL UNFOLD.
THE NUMBERS ARE SIMPLY
STAGGERING.
I WANT TO BRING PEOPLE UP TO
DATE.
AT 2:30 EASTERN, AT LEAST 27
SHOT AND KILLED, MANY OF THEM
CHILDREN THAT'S DAN HARRIS AT
THE SCENE WHO'S BEEN THERE ALL
MORNING LONG.
THE AERIAL VIEWS, THE AMBULANCES
PULLING UP, AS DAN POINTED OUT,
PULLING OUT WITHOUT THEIR
SIRENS.
WE HAVE SEEN GURNEYS, INJURED
VICTIMS LEAVING THESE SCHOOLS,
THESE INCIDENTS ACROSS AMERICA
AND IN THIS CASE ONE OF THE MAIN
DIFFERENCES IS, AS OF RIGHT NOW,
WE ONLY KNOW OF THREE PEOPLE
BEING TREATED AT A LOCAL
HOSPITAL WHICH WOULD LEAVE YOU
TO PREMUM, THE OTHER PEOPLE
INSIDE THAT SCHOOL WHO WERE
TARGETED DIDN'T MAKE IT OUT OF
THE SCHOOL.
THAT NUMBER, MORE THAN TWO DOZEN
PEOPLE INSIDE THAT SCHOOL IS
SIMPLY QUITE FRANKLY THAT WE'LL
HAVE TO GET OUR HEAD AROUND.
THE WORST SCHOOL SHOOTING AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
TO IMAGINE THE AGES OF THESE
CHILDREN, THESE YOUNG FACES
INSIDE THESE CLASS ROOMS AND THE
HORROR THAT THEY WENT THROUGH
THIS MORNING, AND ONE OF THE
THINGS THAT WE STRUCK BY AS WE
HAVE BEEN REPORTING THIS
THROUGHOUT THE AFTERNOON HERE,
AS YOUR WATCHING ABC NEWS LIVE
COVERAGE, THE REACTION OF THE
CHILDREN AND YOU JUXTAPOSE IT
WITH THE ADULTS, WE HEARD FROM
ONE 17-YEAR-OLD BOY WHO SAID I
NEEDED CALMING DOWN MYSELF.
WE HEARD HIM SAY THAT