CHRISTMAS LIGHTS...
ICICLES... SNOW DRIFTS...
DURING THE HOLIDAY SEASON,
THE ENTIRE DISNEYLAND RESORT
IS TRANSFORMED
INTO A WINTER WONDERLAND.
WELCOME TO OUR
"AFV CHRISTMAS SPECTACULAR."
THE GOOD FOLKS AT DISNEYLAND
WERE KIND ENOUGH
TO GIVE US THE KEYS
TO THE MAGIC KINGDOM.
THEY BROUGHT THE DECORATIONS,
WE BROUGHT OUR GREATEST
CHRISTMAS CLIPS OF ALL TIME.
I GUARANTEE YOU WILL NOT
WANT TO REGIFT THESE.
♪ GIBBLE GAL, GIBBLE BELL
♪ GIBBLE ALL WAY
♪ OH, A LA, GEE DA DA
♪ LA LA LEE HEE
(man) SINGING "JINGLE BELLS."
♪ GIBBLE BELL, GIBBLE BALL
♪ GIBBLE ALL WAY
(crying)
♪ OH, WA LA GEE LEE LA
♪ LA LA LEE LEE BYE YA
(man) MERRY CHRISTMAS!
HAPPY BIRTHDAY!
MAYBE SANTA SHOULD TRADE IN
THAT RED SUIT
FOR AN ORANGE LIFE VEST.
(woman) AAH!
(man) WHOO!
OH, SANTA.
LOOK WHO'S HERE TO SEE YOU.
LOOK WHO'S HERE.
HO HO HO HO.
WHO'S HERE?
WHO'S THIS PERSON
COMING TO SEE YOU?
WHO'S THAT?
(gasps)
HO HO HO.
SOME FACES SPEAK
LOUDER THAN WORDS.
SAY "HI, SANTA."
(laughs)
(speaks indistinctly)
WHO'S THAT?
SANTA.
THAT'S SANTA!
HO HO HO!
(indistinct conversations)
A CHRISTMAS PIÑATA?
WHAT IS THIS,
SANTA DE MAYO?
(woman) YOU SAID ONE.
(all scream)
(laughter)
(woman) MY FRIEND RACHEL JUST
GOT A ROUND RING LIKE THAT...
I THINK THE DOG'S JEALOUS
HE DIDN'T GET
AN ENGAGEMENT RING
FOR CHRISTMAS.
(man) UH, PRETTY NICELY,
UH, GIFT-WRAPPED.
BO! OH, GOD,
HE GOT IT IN HIS MOUTH.
(dog growls)
AAH, DON'T--IT'S OUT,
IT'S OUT, IT'S OUT.
IT'S OUT? WHERE IS--
OKAY. IT'S ON THIS.
IT'S RIGHT HERE.
OKAY, OKAY.
(woman) HE CAME, GUYS.
(boy) OH, COOL!
OH, HE DID GET
MURPHY SOMETHING.
COOL!
DADDY...
I GOT A NUT! I GOT A NUT!
HE GOT MURPHY FOOD.
COOL!
I GOT A NUT!
(woman) COOL.
(laughing)
(woman) THE DOG...
OH, OH! ZEUS!
(man) EVERY (bleep) DAY THEY
COME IN HERE
AND (bleep) ON THE (bleep)
PRESENTS!
I HAVE CLEANED UP
FIVE PRESENTS!
CAN I OPEN IT NOW?
(man) WHAT DO YOU GOT, BUD?
IT MIGHT BE A PEEWEE FOOTBALL,
BUT THIS IS A BIG-LEAGUE
THROW.
(crash, laughter)
EVERYBODY KNOWS
THAT SANTA CLAUS
DOESN'T LIKE CHILDREN
WHO ARE NAUGHTY.
"BERGERON CLAUS"--
WELL, I TEND TO CUT THEM
A LITTLE MORE SLACK--
AFTER ALL, I HAVE
A CHRISTMAS SHOW TO HOST.
AND THOSE NAUGHTY KIDS--
THEY'VE BEEN PRETTY NICE
TO "AFV."
WHILE YOU'RE WATERING THE TREE,
YOU MIGHT AS WELL
WATER YOUR DAD.
JOSHUA! (laughs)
(man) THEY'RE ALL FULL.
THE STOCKINGS WERE HUNG
ON THE CHIMNEY WITH CARE...
NOT IN THIS VIDEO.
(laughs) OH, THANK YOU.
YOU ARE... THANK YOU, DARLING.
OKAY, WATCH IT.
IT'S GLASS, SWEETIE.
OH!
(man and woman laugh)
(cheers)
(man speaks indistinctly
in amplified voice)
WE'VE GOTTA WORK ON THIS
MICROPHONE, THOUGH, DON'T WE?
IT'D BE A REAL DISTRACTION.
THANK YOU, BOYS.
CAN YOU GO TO YOUR SEATS NOW?
(laughter)
OKAY.
THIS--THIS WAS THE ONE
THAT DIDN'T WANT TO COME UP
A MINUTE AGO.
(laughs)
UH-OH!
(speaks indistinctly)
HE'S UP--LET'S GET DAD
UP HERE... (laughs)
OH! HE GOT HIM!
GIVE HIM A HAND! HEY!
YOU'RE PROBABLY SPENDING
A LOT OF TIME
WORRYING ABOUT WHAT TO GET
YOUR FAMILY FOR CHRISTMAS.
BUT DON'T FORGET THE FURRIEST
MEMBER OF YOUR FAMILY--
YOUR DOG.
NOW, HE MIGHT NOT UNDERSTAND
WHY YOU GOT HIM A GIFT,
BUT IT'LL GET HIS TAIL WAGGING
JUST THE SAME.
CHRISTMAS--IT'S NOT JUST
FOR HUMANS ANYMORE.
DA-DA?
DA-DA.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THE LITTLE
GIRL GOT FOR CHRISTMAS,
BUT THE PUPPY GOT A CLOSE-UP.
♪
NOT EVERYBODY LOVES
DAD'S NEW SLIPPERS.
THEY FIT.
(laughs)
SLIPPERS. LOOK AT THAT.
GONNA WEAR THESE TO WORK.
AAH!
(dog barking)
WHOA! WHOA! WHOA!
I GOT IT.
(barking)
(man) WHAT IS IN THERE?
(man) A BLANKET?
YEAH.
LOOK AGAIN.
LOOK!
(woman) OH, MY GOD.
(laughter)
(woman) OH, HONEY.
(man laughing)
OH. BE NICE.
IS THAT A PUPPY?
YEAH! WOW! (laughs)
WOW!
(knock on door)
♪
WHO CARES ABOUT JACK FROST
NIPPING AT YOUR NOSE
WHEN BARKLEY'S NIPPING
AT YOUR HEELS?
HO HO!
(dog barks)
AAH!
(woman) AAH!
OH!
(dog growls)
ONE WAY TO GUARANTEE
A WHITE CHRISTMAS--
LET YOUR DOBERMAN CHEW
ON A CAN OF SHAVING CREAM.
(can hisses)
(woman) OH, MY GOD.
(laughs)
(indistinct conversations)
I'M HERE IN TOWN SQUARE
BY THE GIANT CHRISTMAS TREE.
THIS TREE IS COVERED
WITH 62,000 LIGHTS
AND 2,000 ORNAMENTS.
THAT MAY NOT BE A WORLD RECORD,
BUT IT'S A RECORD FOR OUR SHOW.
IT'S THE LONGEST WE'VE SHOWN
A CHRISTMAS TREE
WITHOUT SOMEONE FALLING
ON IT, INTO IT, OR UNDER IT.
SOMETHING WE'LL PUT AN END
TO RIGHT ABOUT NOW.
(Frank Sinatra's "We Wish You
the Merriest" playing)
♪ WE WISH YOU
THE MERRIEST, THE MERRIEST ♪
♪ THE MERRIEST,
YES, THE MERRIEST ♪
(woman) OH! OH!
♪ WE WISH YOU THE MERRIEST,
THE MERRIEST ♪
♪ THE MERRIEST YULE CHEER
♪ WE WISH YOU THE HAPPIEST,
THE HAPPIEST ♪
♪ THE HAPPIEST,
YES, THE HAPPIEST ♪
♪ WE WISH YOU THE HAPPIEST,
THE HAPPIEST ♪
♪ THE HAPPIEST NEW YEAR
♪ MAY YOUR TREE BE FILLED
WITH HAPPINESS ♪
AAH!
(crash)
♪ HAPPINESS AND FRIENDLINESS
FOR ALL ♪
♪ MAY YOUR HEART
BE FILLED WITH CHEERFULNESS ♪
♪ HAPPINESS
AND CHEERFULNESS FOR ALL ♪
♪ WE WISH YOU THE HAPPIEST,
THE HAPPIEST ♪
♪ THE HAPPIEST
AAH!
♪ YES, THE HAPPIEST
♪ WE WISH YOU THE MERRIEST,
THE MERRIEST ♪
♪ THE MERRIEST YULE CHEER
(woman) AAH!
♪ AND THE HAPPIEST
♪ I SAY THE FRIENDLIEST
♪ AND THE CHEERIEST
♪ WE MEAN THE MERRIEST
♪ NEW YEAR
(woman) OH, ALAN!
(bells clatter)
♪
They're looking left,
then right, then left again.
They're not texting or
tweeting, no sir.
They're breaking for
squirrels, and then some.
And their deductibles are
disappearing.
Because Nationwide
Insurance members
who add Vanishing Deductible
get $100 off
for every year
of safe driving.
We put members first, because we
don't have shareholders.
Join the Nation
that hangs up and drives.
♪ Nationwide Is On Your Side
♪
(gates creak,
sinister laugh)
(screaming and laughter)
THIS TIME OF YEAR,
JACK SKELLINGTON
AND THE GANG FROM TIM BURTON'S
"THE NIGHTMARE BEFORE CHRISTMAS"
MOVE INTO THE HAUNTED MANSION
AND ADD A LITTLE MAYHEM
TO THE MACABRE.
AND WHEN HALLOWEEN
TAKES OVER CHRISTMAS,
THE RESULTS ARE DISASTROUS.
OF COURSE, CHRISTMAS CAN
SOMETIMES TURN INTO A DISASTER
WITHOUT ANY OUTSIDE HELP.
IT SHOWS MY NAME--
J-O-S-H-U-A.
(woman) WELL, OPEN IT UP.
(rustling)
GIVE IT HERE
AND LET ME--
(man) YOU'RE GONNA KNOCK
YOUR TEETH OUT.
AAH!
THEY BOTH CAME OUT
AT THE SAME TIME?!
LOOK!
LOOK HERE!
GOOD JOB, BUBBA!
(woman) THANK YOU.
(woman) YOU'RE VERY,
VERY WELCOME.
OH, LOOK AT THAT.
(man) LOOK AT HIM.
HE CERTAINLY IS
A GIFTED CHILD.
UH-OH.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THEY GOT HIM,
BUT I THINK HE LIKES IT.
(laughter)
♪ 'TWAS THE NIGHT
BEFORE CHRISTMAS ♪
♪ AND ALL THROUGH THE HOUSE
♪ NOT A CREATURE WAS STIRRING
♪ NOT EVEN A MOUSE
♪ ALL THE STOCKINGS
WERE HANGING ♪
♪ BY THE CHIMNEY WITH CARE
♪ IN HOPES THAT ST. NICHOLAS
WOULD SOON BE THERE ♪
♪ HE'S BRINGING LOTS OF TOYS
♪ FOR GIRLS AND BOYS
♪ BUT WAIT UNTIL YOU SEE
♪ THAT MERRY CHRISTMAS TREE
...DISPOSE OF SOMETHING
THAT I HATE!
(man) WHAT'S THAT?
MY PRINTER.
WHY DO YOU HATE
YOU PRINTER?
BECAUSE...
IT'S A PIECE OF... (bleep)
EXCUSE ME?
IT IS.
IT'S BEEN DRIVING ME CRAZY
FOR THE LAST TWO YEARS.
YEAH.
(woman) YOU SAID... (bleep)
SANTA BROUGHT ME
A NEW PRINTER.
SANTA BROUGHT YOU
A NEW PRINTER?
ONE...
(laughs)
TWO...
THREE!
(clatter)
OW!
OW! OW! OW! OW!
OW. OW. OW. OW.
OW. OW. OW.
SHE HIT ME WITH IT.
OW. OW.
IN THE MOVIE,
TIM BURTON'S "THE NIGHTMARE
BEFORE CHRISTMAS,"
JACK DISCOVERED
HE COULD PUT ON SANTA'S SUIT
BUT HE COULDN'T QUITE
PULL OFF CHRISTMAS.
TURNS OUT THE GANG
IN HALLOWEEN TOWN
HAVE A PRETTY TWISTED IDEA
OF WHAT MAKES A GOOD GIFT.
CHECK OUT SOME OTHER PEOPLE
WHO GOT LOUSY GIFTS.
GRANTED, THEIR GIFTS
DIDN'T COME TO LIFE
AND TRY TO EAT THEM.
BUT THEY WERE STILL
PRETTY DARN LOUSY.
WHAT KID DOESN'T LOVE
GETTING CLOTHES FOR CHRISTMAS?
(laughter)
ALL OF THEM.
(man) NICHOLAS?
HEY! CHRISTMAS IS OVER?
(woman) OH!
(man) YOU WANT YOUR PRESENT?
OKAY. GO OPEN IT UP.
THIS MIGHT NOT BE
A GREAT GIFT...
ARE YOU EXCITED?
BUT AT LEAST IT'S SOMETHING
HE CAN USE.
(laughing)
WELL, WHAT DO YOU HAVE
TO SAY?
(thud)
YEAH, THROW THE PAPER AWAY.
YOU GOTTA DO THAT.
WAH!
MAYBE IT'S BEST
TO OPEN YOUR GIFT
BEFORE YOU HIT SOMEONE
OVER THE HEAD WITH IT.
BAM! BAM!
OH!
(laughs)
YOU IDIOT!
DOING IT TO EVERYBODY.
I CAN'T EVEN SEE STRAIGHT.
LOOK, I WAS--I WAS JUST
GONNA SAY, "BAM! BAM!"
LIKE ON "THE FLINTSTONES."
LOOK AT... (laughing)
(laughs)
I CAN DO IT.
(woman) YAY!
WHOA.
THAT'S NICE.
WHOA!
THAT'S AWESOME!
MOM GOT A NEW TRASH CAN.
YOU OPEN IT WITH YOUR FOOT
AND STOP IT WITH YOUR FACE.
(clang)
(laughter)
OOH.
(man) OH, GOD.
MOM...
(man) NO, THERE'S
A LIGHT ON IN THERE.
HER CHRISTMAS WISH
WAS FOR SOME FISH.
GO AHEAD.
(woman) LET ME TURN
THE LIGHT ON.
OKAY, TURN THE LIGHT ON NOW.
ARE THEY DEAD?
(woman) NO.
DON'T TELL ME THAT.
I THINK THIS...
(boy) THEY WOULD BE FLOATING
ON TOP OF THERE.
(laughter)
(boy laughs)
THEY'RE ALREADY DEAD.
FOR MOST KIDS,
HAUNTED MANSION HOLIDAY
IS PRETTY SCARY.
FOR OTHER KIDS,
THE SCARIEST THING AROUND...
IS SANTA CLAUS.
(indistinct conversations)
THEY EXPECTED SANTA
TO COME DOWN THE CHIMNEY,
NOT THROUGH THE WINDOW.
(man) OH, DEAR! LOOK HERE!
(children) AAH!
(laughter)
(woman) OH, MY GOD.
(man) WHAT WAS THAT?
(woman) BABY! HI! HELLO!
I THINK
SHE'S SANTA CLAUS-TROPHOBIC.
OOH. LOOK, LOOK, LOOK, LOOK.
(laughter)
(woman) LOOK, HE'S HERE.
(man) LOOK WHAT SANTA CLAUS
GOT. HO-HO-HO!
(man) AW, LOOK. SANTA CLAUS
BROUGHT A DOGGIE.
SANTA CLAUS WOULDN'T HURT
A LITTLE DOGGIE.
COME HERE, LITTLE GIRL.
NO, I DON'T WANT TO!
(laughter)
I BROUGHT YOU A PRESENT.
HO-HO-HO!
WAIT, LISTEN--
(child crying)
I WANT--I WANNA TELL YOU
THE SANTA METHOD.
LISTEN.
THIS IS THE SANTA METHOD.
(man) ALL RIGHT.
ARE YOU READY?
WHAT'S THE SANTA METHOD?
ALL RIGHT. THE SANTA METHOD
IS YOU--IS I COUNT TO THREE...
RIGHT.
AND YOU GO "ONE, TWO, THREE,"
PUT 'EM ON,
MOVE OUT OF THE WAY,
SNAP.
(woman) OKAY.
BUT DON'T--DON'T TELEGRAPH IT.
ONE, TWO, THREE!
(children screaming)
(laughter)
I'M SURE THIS
HAS HAPPENED TO YOU.
YOU GET A GIFT YOU REALLY LOVE
ON CHRISTMAS MORNING,
AND BY DECEMBER 26th,
IT'S BROKEN!
GIFT BAG TO TRASH BAG
IN 24 HOURS.
WELL, THIS NEXT KID
IS SO WORRIED ABOUT
HIS TOYS BEING BROKEN,
HE WON'T LET ANYONE TOUCH THEM.
(speaking indistinctly)
(man laughs)
OKAY, I'M GONNA PLAY
WITH SPIDER-MAN THEN.
YOU CAN'T.
THAT'S BREAKABLE STUFF.
THAT'S BREAKABLE? (laughs)
THERE'S LOTS
OF BREAKABLE STUFF...
THAT ARE BREAKABLE.
ARE YOU SHARING?
OKAY, I'M GONNA PLAY
WITH THIS.
IT'S VERY BREAKABLE.
VERY BREAKABLE.
VERY BREAK--
YES, THAT'S VERY BREAKABLE.
OKAY, WELL, I'M GONNA PLAY
WITH THIS.
THIS ISN'T BREAKABLE.
OKAY?
YEAH, THAT'S BREAKABLE, TOO.
(laughter)
(speaks indistinctly)
HOW ABOUT THIS?
CAN I PLAY WITH THIS?
NO, THAT'S MY PURSE.
(laughing)
♪
A LOWER PRICE ON YOUR GIFTS.
GETTING THEM HOME?
WOW.
YEAH.
THAT'S ANOTHER STORY.
CITI PRICE REWIND.
SEE HOW YOU CAN SAVE
AT CITI.COM/PRICEREWIND.
PREGO?!
BUT I'VE BOUGHT RAGU FOR YEARS.
[ Thinking ] WONDER WHAT OTHER
QUESTIONABLE CHOICES I'VE MADE?
I CHOOSE DATE NUMBER 2!
WHOOO!
[ sigh of relief ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHOOSE TASTE. CHOOSE PREGO.
HI.
DELUXE DREAM VILLAGE.
THAT'S MY FAVORITE.
[ Male Announcer ] SOME PEOPLE
REALLY LOVE THEIR JOBS.
OK.
HAVE A SUPER SPARKLY DAY!
AND SOME PEOPLE
JUST LOVE TO SAVE MONEY.
SEE HOW YOU CAN SAVE
AT CITI.COM/PRICEREWIND.
♪
YOU KNOW WHAT I LOVE
ABOUT SANTA?
THE GUY DRIVES A SLEIGH.
MORE PEOPLE SHOULD
DRIVE SLEIGHS.
THEY'RE QUIET,
THEY DON'T USE GAS,
SO THEY'RE ENVIRONMENTALLY
FRIENDLY.
AND WHEN'S THE LAST TIME
YOU HEARD ABOUT A PRESIDENT
HAVING TO BAIL OUT
THE SLEIGH INDUSTRY?
(laughs)
HERE IS WHY SLEIGH RIDES
AND HAIRPIN TURNS
DO NOT MIX.
(bells jingling)
(screaming)
(laughter)
SHE THINKS IT'S A SLEIGH RIDE.
HE THINKS IT'S A RODEO.
(horse whinnying)
EVERYBODY KNOWS SANTA'S SLEIGH
IS A ONE-PERSON VEHICLE.
(shouts and laughs)
(creaking)
(screams)
(laughing)
(woman shouts indistinctly)
AT THIS RACETRACK,
DID SANTA WIN, PLACE,
OR SHOW HO HO?
HOW IS SHE
GOING TO DELIVER TOYS
TO ALL THE CHILDREN
IN THE WORLD
IF SHE CAN'T STAY
IN THE SLEIGH?
SOMETHING TELLS ME
THE REAL SANTA'S JOB IS SAFE.
WITH ALL THE STRESS
AND RUSHING AROUND
DURING THE HOLIDAYS,
IT'S EASY TO FORGET
WHAT CHRISTMAS REALLY MEANS--
PEACE ON EARTH.
GOODWILL TOWARDS MEN.
A TIME TO PUT AN END
TO ALL CONFLICTS...
AFTER THIS NEXT "VS."
ANYWAY.
WE'VE GOT A HECK
OF A BATTLE TONIGHT!
YOU GOTTA SMILE.
(all laugh)
(boxing ring bell rings)
TONIGHT ON "VS.,"
SANTA VS. FROSTY!
SANTA'S NOT GOING DOWN
THE CHIMNEY,
BUT HE IS GOING DOWN!
BUT FROSTY COMES TO LIFE,
AND THESE KIDS WISH HE HADN'T.
SANTA WANTS TO FIGHT FROSTY
WITH FIRE.
(whoosh)
OH, BURN, BABY, BURN!
BUT FROSTY'S GETTING
A LITTLE HOT UNDER THE COLLAR.
(loud pop)
(laughter)
(pop)
SANTA TRADES IN
HIS REINDEER POWER
FOR HORSEPOWER.
FROSTY'S RUNNING OUT OF TIME...
AND OUT OF STAGE!
(audience gasps)
(thud)
AND THE WINNER IS...
(bell dings)
SANTA!
(cheers)
JOIN US NEXT TIME
WHEN THE JOLLY FAT MAN
TAKES ON...
(woman gasps)
OH, MY GOD!
ON "VS"!
(screaming)
ISN'T THIS SWEET?
BUT WOULDN'T IT BE GREAT
IF ADULTS COULD SIT
ON SANTA'S LAP
AND ASK FOR THE THINGS WE WANT?
DEAR SANTA,
I WANT
MY ORIGINAL HAIR COLOR BACK.
I WANT BROCCOLI
TO TASTE LIKE PEPPERONI PIZZA.
AND I WANNA BE HIP
INSTEAD OF JUST NEEDING
A NEW ONE.
SO HAVE FUN WHILE YOU CAN.
AND I WANT YOU TO LEARN
AS BEST YOU CAN.
THE ONLY WAY YOU CAN DO THAT
IS IF YOU DO YOUR HOMEWORK.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY.
THERE'S NO SHORTCUTS.
NO SHORTCUTS.
WHAT WOULD THE SHORTCUT BE
IF THERE WAS ONE?
WELL, IF THERE WAS ONE...
(man laughs)
(laughs)
MASON.
IS THAT YOUR SISTER OR BROTHER?
BOY, DO...
I DO?
WHAT DO YOU WANT
FOR CHRISTMAS?
(laughter)
I KNOW, BUT YOU HAVE
TO REMEMBER SANTA'S VERY OLD.
IF YOU'RE THE SAME SHAPE
AS SANTA,
YOU PROBABLY SHOULDN'T
JUMP IN HIS LAP.
(man) OH!
(laughter)
OH, YOU ANIMAL.
(laughter continues)
AND WHAT IS YOUR NAME?
(woman) SPEAK UP, HONEY.
NATHAN.
I CAN'T PRONOUNCE IT. OKAY.
OKAY, THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
SAY YOUR NAME OUT LOUD NOW.
NO?
YEAH.
YEAH?
OKAY. AND, UH,
WE'RE HAVING FUN, EH?
♪
AND THIS IS
THE NOKIA LUMIA 920 FROM AT&T.
IT'S GOT LIVE TILES
SO ALL MY STUFF'S
ALWAYS RIGHT THERE IN REAL-TIME.
IT'S LIKE
THE ULTIMATE PERSONAL ASSISTANT.
BUT I'M ME,
AND ME NEEDS HANDLERS.
SO I HIRED TODD
TO HANDLE IT FOR ME.
TODD, GIMME THAT HOLLYWOOD NEWS!
WHAT'S HAPPENING ON TWITTER?
YOU'RE TRENDING!
YES!
YOU CAN'T HAVE A TODD,
BUT YOU CAN HAVE YOUR
OWN PERSONAL ASSISTANT.
I GUESS
YOU COULD CALL IT TODD.
[ Male Announcer ] THE NEW
NOKIA LUMIA 920 WITH LIVE TILES
THAT DELIVER WHAT YOU WANT
IN REAL TIME.
ONLY FROM AT&T.
RETHINK POSSIBLE.
FOR CENTURIES."
♪
THIS LEVIAN COLLECTION
IS AMAZING.
MAYBE IT'S TIME
TO START YOUR OWN.
[ Female Announcer ]
KAY JEWELERS PRESENTS
TODAY'S LEVIAN COLLECTION...
[ gasps ]
FEATURING EXCLUSIVE
LEVIAN CHOCOLATE DIAMONDS.
FROM THE LEVIAN FAMILY -
WHERE THE LATEST IN FASHION
MEETS FINE JEWELRY.
ONE MORE REASON KAY
IS THE NUMBER-ONE JEWELRY STORE
IN AMERICA.
IT'S...
A WORK OF ART?
♪ EVERY KISS BEGINS WITH KAY
AND ST. JUDE CHILDREN'S
RESEARCH HOSPITAL CREATED
A SPECIAL BRAIN TUMOR
TREATMENT JUST FOR ARIANNA.
OUR BOLD, NEW PROCEDURE IS
HELPING TO EXTEND HER LIFE...
AND GIVE HER FAMILY HOPE.
LOOK WHAT I MADE.
BEAUTIFUL...
HUG YOUR CHILD TONIGHT...
GIVE THANKS FOR THE HEALTHY
KIDS IN YOUR LIFE.
AND GIVE TO THOSE WHO ARE
NOT. GO TO ST. JUDE DOT ORG
OR SHOP WHERE EVER YOU SEE
THE ST. JUDE LOGO.
TO TELL REAL PEOPLE ABOUT
OUR NEW 15 UNDER $15 MENU.
OH MY GOODNESS!
OH MY GOSH,
THIS LOOKS AMAZING!
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR NEW MAINE STAYS!
15 ENTREES UNDER $15,
SEAFOOD, CHICKEN AND MORE!
OO! THE TILAPIA
WITH ROASTED VEGETABLES!
I'M ACTUALLY LOOKING AT
THE WOOD GRILLED CHICKEN
WITH PORTOBELLO WINE SAUCE.
THAT PORK CHOP
WAS GREAT!
NO MORE
FAST FOOD FRIDAY'S!
WE'RE GOING TO GO
TO RED LOBSTER.
YEP.
[ Male Announcer ]
COME TRY OUR NEW MENU
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY!
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
SALAD, SANDWICHES, AND MORE.
with Lively Colombian.
It's a morning breeze
smooth as Black Silk.
With Folgers Gourmet Selections
K-Cup packs
You can turn any day gourmet.
New roasts, a new look...
available
where you buy groceries.
CAMPBELL'S HAS 24 NEW SOUPS
THAT WILL MAKE IT DROP OVER,
AND OVER AGAIN.
♪
FROM JAMMIN' JERK CHICKEN,
TO CREAMY GOUDA BISQUE.
SEE WHAT'S NEW FROM CAMPBELL'S.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
♪
YOU THINK DECORATING YOUR HOUSE
FOR CHRISTMAS IS A LOT OF WORK?
IMAGINE DECORATING
IT'S A SMALL WORLD HOLIDAY.
I DID A QUICK COUNT
OF THE LIGHTBULBS HERE
AND I GOT A BAZILLION.
OF COURSE, I'M ROUNDING OFF.
IT MAY BE A SMALL WORLD,
BUT IT WOULD STILL TAKE
A WHOLE LOT OF TINSEL
TO MAKE IT SPARKLE.
(dance music playing)
(Tom) LOOKS LIKE HE PROMISED
MRS. CLAUS
HE WOULDN'T DANCE
WITH ANYONE ELSE.
♪
MOM, PUT THE CAMERA NEAR ME,
AND I'LL SHOW YOU SOMETHIN'.
(woman) WHAT?
I SAW SANTA CLAUS.
HE PEEKED IN OUR WINDOW.
HE WENT DOWN ON OUR DECK.
HE WAS PEEKING.
I JUST SAW HIM.
DID YOU SEE HIM?
(woman laughs) NO. HOW COULD
I SEE HIM?
I JUST SAW HIM!
HE JUST PEEKED.
I SAW HIM! REALLY, I DID!
HE PEEKED. I SAW HIM.
I--HE PEEKED.
I SAW HIM.
(woman) OOH.
(gasps)
GOT THAT ONE ON VIDEO.
♪
(piano playing)
(off-key) ♪ HOLY NIGHT
♪ STARS ARE BRIGHT
♪ AT YOUR LIGHT
♪ ROUND YON VIRGIN
♪ MOTHER AND CHILD
♪ HOLY INFANT SO...
(man) WHAT'S THE MATTER?
(girl) SHE WANTED A PHONE.
WHAT?
SHE WANTED A PHONE.
PHONE?
WELL, MAYBE NEXT YEAR.
(woman) HMM.
SHE'S DISAPPOINTED
'CAUSE SHE DIDN'T GET
THE CELL PHONE SHE WANTED...
OR DID SHE?
(buzzing)
WHAT IS THAT?
(ringtone playing)
I GOT A PHONE!
(crying) I GOT A PHONE!
DID YOU HURT YOURSELF
WHEN YOU DID THAT?
OH, MY GOD! I GOT A...
(laughter)
IF MOM CAN WEAR MOM JEANS,
WHY CAN'T GRANDPA
WEAR GRANDPA SLIPPERS?
(laughter)
(man) HEY, UNCLE JIM!
(woman) OH, MY GOD!
HE'S GROWING OLD!
LOOK AT HIS MOUTH, THOUGH.
YOU KNOW WHAT'S AMAZING?
ON THE IT'S A SMALL WORLD
HOLIDAY ATTRACTION,
CHILDREN FROM VIRTUALLY
EVERY COUNTRY AROUND THE WORLD
SING AND DANCE
IN PERFECT HARMONY.
BUT ON "AFV,"
CHILDREN FROM THE SAME CLASSROOM
CAN BARELY MAKE IT THROUGH
A SIMPLE CHRISTMAS CAROL.
(boy yelling)
♪ ...WATCH OUT,
YOU BETTER NOT CRY ♪
♪ YOU BETTER NOT POUT,
I'M TELLING YOU WHY ♪
♪ SANTA CLAUS IS COMING
♪ TO TOWN
TO TOWN!
(laughter)
♪ HE'S CHECKING IT TWICE
♪ HE'S GONNA FIND OUT
WHO'S NAUGHTY AND NICE ♪
♪ SANTA CLAUS IS COMING
♪ TO TOWN
TO TOWN!
(laughter, applause)
♪ HE KNOWS WHEN YOU'RE AWAKE
♪ HE KNOWS WHEN YOU ARE
BAD OR GOOD ♪
GOOD OR BAD! ♪
♪ SO BE GOOD
FOR GOODNESS' SAKE ♪
SO BE GOOD... OR BAD!
(laughter)
♪ YOU BETTER NOT POUT,
I'M TELLING YOU WHY ♪
♪ SANTA CLAUS IS COMING
♪ TO TOWN
TO TOWN!
(laughter)
THIS CLIP IS
ONE PART ALLERGIC REACTION...
(sneezes)
AND ONE PART COMIC REACTION.
(woman and children)
♪ MARY RODE A DONKEY
♪ GOING TO BETHLEHEM
♪ JOSEPH WALKED BESIDE HER
♪ BESIDE HER, BESIDE HER
♪ GOING TO BETHLEHEM
♪ HAPPY NEW YEAR
♪ WE WISH YOU
A MERRY CHRISTMAS ♪
♪ AND A HAPPY NEW YEAR
♪ WE WISH YOU
A MERRY CHRISTMAS ♪
♪ AND A HAPPY NEW YEAR
♪ JINGLE BELL, JINGLE BELL,
JINGLE BELL ROCK ♪
OH, HE'S FEELING A LOT MORE
THAN THE CHRISTMAS SPIRIT.
(woman laughing)
♪ DANCING AND PRANCING
♪ IN JINGLE BELL SQUARE
♪ IN THE FROSTY AIR
(laughing)
♪ WHAT A BRIGHT TIME,
IT'S THE RIGHT TIME ♪
♪ TO ROCK THE NIGHT AWAY
(whispering) STOP IT! STOP IT!
♪ JINGLE BELL TIME
IS A SWELL TIME ♪
ONE THING THAT'S FUN
ABOUT A WHITE CHRISTMAS
IS PLAYING IN THE SNOW.
NOW LET'S FACE IT--
SNOWBALL FIGHTS
ARE A LOT MORE FUN
THAN A SNOWBALL
TRUCE FOLLOWED BY
A LENGTHY, DRAWN-OUT
SNOWBALL PEACE PROCESS.
CHECK OUT THIS COLD WAR.
(Liszt's "Hungarian Rhapsody
No. 2" playing)
(glass shatters)
OH, OH!
OH!
OOH, LA LA!
AAH!
(laughter)
(grunts)
(yelling)
WHOO!
AAH!
OHH! AAH!
AAH! OH, MY!
AAH!
OH!
(man) OH, MY GOODNESS!
WHOA.
(laughter)
AAH! WHOA!
(woman) AAH!
(laughter)
AAH!
OH! UHH!
♪
YES YOU DID,
YES YOU DID.    NO I DIDN'T,
NO I DIDN'T.
YES YOU DID.
DID NOT.
[ Male Announcer ]
FIND SOME PEACE THIS HOLIDAY.
GET AN 8 PIECE MEAL
NOW WITH A DOZEN
DELICIOUS COOKIES
BAKED IN-STORE.
THE KFC FESTIVE FEAST.
ALL FOR JUST $19.99.
TODAY TASTES SO GOOD.
HI VICTOR!
MOM?
I KNOW YOU GOT TO GO
IN A MINUTE
BUT THIS IS
A REAL QUICK MEAL,
THAT'S PERFECT FOR TWO!
CAMPBELL'S CHUNKY BEEF
WITH COUNTRY VEGETABLES,
POURED OVER RICE!
[ Male Announcer ]
CAMPBELL'S CHUNKY SOUP.
IT FILLS YOU UP RIGHT.
♪
LET'S FACE IT--
EVERY KID KNOWS WHAT
HE OR SHE WANTS FOR CHRISTMAS.
BUT FOR SOME KIDS,
IT MIGHT BE QUICKER
IF THEY JUST LIST THE THINGS
THEY DON'T WANT.
WHAT WOULD YOU
LIKE FOR CHRISTMAS?
OPEN UP THE OTHER FACTORY.
WE NEED SOME.
AND A POLICE ACADEMY...
IS THAT ALL YOU WANT?
HUH?
NOTHING ELSE?
OH, YOU'RE GONNA SAY
GOOD-BYE?
YOU HAVEN'T FINISHED YET,
HAVE YOU?
THAT'S WHAT I THOUGHT.
YEAH.
I THINK THE BEST GIFTS OF ALL
ARE THE FUNNY THINGS
THAT KIDS SAY OVER THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO WRAP THEM,
YOU NEVER HAVE TO RETURN THEM
FOR A DIFFERENT SIZE,
AND IF YOU GET THEM ON VIDEO,
THEY ARE THE GIFTS
THAT KEEP ON GIVING
YEAR AFTER YEAR AFTER YEAR.
(woman) TREY...
(laughter)
GRANDMA?
(speaks indistinctly)
I KNOW WHAT IT IS.
IT'S RIGHT HERE.
(woman) OH.
NOT ANYMORE. OKAY... (laughs)
(laughs)
(paper rustling)
(woman) WHAT IS IT?
(laughter)
(man) OH, BOY.
NOTHING LIKE THOSE THINGS.
(man) YEAH. OH, YEAH.
(man) ANOTHER CANDY CANE.
LET ME UNWRAP A PRESENT
BEFORE HE DOES ALL OF THEM.
OH, HE WON'T--
HE DOESN'T--
ALL RIGHT!
(woman laughs)
AAH!
I LOVE THESE.
(woman)
OH, YOU WANTED LIPSTICK?
NOT A BICYCLE?
(girl) OW.
YEAH, IT'S GOT
MY FAVORITE ANIMAL ON IT.
(gasps)
(laughter)
(man laughs)
YOU BETTER GIVE HIM
A HUG FOR THAT.
THAT WAS MEAN, RYAN.
(laughter)
(woman speaks indistinctly)
A LOT OF THINGS HAVE MADE
CHRISTMAS WHAT IT IS TODAY--
CHRISTMAS PRESENTS--GREAT IDEA.
CHRISTMAS COOKIES--GREAT IDEA.
MISTLETOE--EXCELLENT IDEA.
NOW THESE NEXT VIDEOS FEATURE
SOME PRETTY BAD IDEAS...
BUT THEY WORK FOR US.
(news program theme music
playing)
PLUMBING THE DEPTHS
OF OUR IGNORANCE, IT'S...
("Jingle Bells" playing)
(crack)
(screams)
♪
(laughter)
(woman) THAT'LL GET IT.
THAT'LL GET IT.
(laughter)
DO THAT ONE, JUDY.
♪
(man) ♪ TA-DA
(woman gasps)
OH, MY GOD.
OH, NO... (laughs)
♪
(passes gas)
THERE GOES SANTA.
(laughs)
THIS HAS BEEN "AFV's"...
THERE ARE SO MANY PLACES HERE
TO GET GIFTS.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT
THE PERFECT GIFT IS
FOR A SMALL CHILD?
ONE THEY CAN ACTUALLY SEE
WHEN THEY OPEN IT.
OKAY, GO AHEAD
AND LIFT UP THE BOX.
(grunts)
(man chuckles)
IT'S EMPTY.
IT WAS JUST A BOX!
(man) IT WAS JUST A BOX.
NO, IT ISN'T.
WELL, OPEN IT, THEN.
I CAN'T OPEN IT.
HERE, I'LL GET
YOU STARTED.
IT'S BISCUIT!
(woman laughs)
YOU GOT ME BISCUIT!
NO WAY! NO WAY!
LOOK AT, MOMMY,
HE BROUGHT ME BISCUIT!
(laughs) OH, MY GOODNESS!
WHERE IS IT?
OPEN THE BOX!
IS HE IN THERE?
OPEN THE BOX.
KENNY, OPEN THE BOX.
(dog barks)
A COOL PRESENT... (gasps)
(laughter)
HEY, IT'S MAGIC!
(barks)
CHRISTMAS IS THE BEST TIME
OF YEAR FOR SO MANY REASONS.
IT'S ALSO THE BEST TIME
OF YEAR FOR VIDEOS.
YOU'RE WATCHING THE SHOW.
YOU KNOW I'M RIGHT.
SO WHAT ARE YOU WAITING FOR?
GRAB A CAMERA.
RECORD YOUR FAMILY
TRIMMING THE TREE,
OPENING PRESENTS,
DIGGING INTO CHRISTMAS DINNER.
DON'T LET ANOTHER
CHRISTMAS SEASON GO BY
WITHOUT CAPTURING
YOUR $100,000 MOMENT.
JUST UPLOAD YOUR VIDEO
TO afv.com,
OR SEND IT TO US AT "AFV"...
FOR FULL CONTEST RULES,
LOG ON TO afv.com
OR WRITE THE ADDRESS ABOVE.
CHRISTMAS IS ABOUT SHARING,
SO WHY NOT SHARE
YOUR CHRISTMAS VIDEOS
WITH THE WORLD?
OK KIDS, LUNCH.
BRAVO. BRAV...OH. IS THAT LUNCH?
YOU DESERVE A LITTLE
MOZZAREL-LA-LA-LA-LA-LA-LA.
WENDY'S.
GASP.
IS THERE SUPPOSED TO BE A PUDDLE
AROUND THE SNOWMAN'S FEET?
NO.
WENDY'S MOZZARELLA
CHICKEN SUPREME.
CRISP CHICKEN,
LOTS OF MOZZARELLA,
AND A RICH PARMESAN SAUCE.
MAKING TASTES THAT
MAKE THE SEASON.
THAT'S WENDY'S WAY.
NOW THAT'S BETTER.
GET A $10 TOYS-R-US
GIFT CARD OFFER
WHEN YOU PURCHASE A KID'S MEAL.
SEE OFFER FOR DETAILS.
But we can eliminate
deductibles.
Nationwide Insurance members who
add vanishing deductible
get $100 off for
every year of safe driving.
We put members first
because we don't have
shareholders.
Join the Nation where
deductibles go...
♪ Nationwide Is On Your Side
FAMILY PARTY IN FIFTEEN.
OK LET'S DO IT!
[ Female Announcer ] IT'S
THE HOLIDAY SALE AT PAYLESS.
GRAB ALL THE STYLES YOU NEED
IN A FLASH
AT FESTIVELY LOW PRICES.
RIGHT NOW AT PAYLESS.
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
DISCOVER THE TEMPTING LAYERS
OF FERRERO ROCHER.
A WHOLE HAZELNUT,
SMOOTH CHOCOLATY CREAM
INSIDE A WAFER SHELL,
COVERED IN MILK CHOCOLATE
AND HAZELNUT PIECES.
♪
FERRERO ROCHER.
MAKE YOUR MOMENTS GOLDEN.
YOU SPEND ALL DAY COOKING IT.
SO WHY SPEND EVEN A MOMENT
CONSIDERING ANY BROTH
BUT SWANSON?
THE BROTH COOKS TRUST MOST
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
IN STUFFING AND MORE,
THE SECRET IS SWANSON.
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
We I love my phone.r contract
plan for Net10 Wireless.
You could keep your phone
and number.
But for half of what we pay now.
Half?
Really good progress today.
Welcome to the next generation
of family plans.
Visit Net10Wireless.com.
WHEN YOU GIVE A CHILD A TOY,
IT HAS TO WORK.
♪ MAKE JUST ONE SOMEONE HAPPY
AND WHEN
IT'S A TOYS FOR TOTS CHILD,
WELL, WHAT COULD BE
MORE IMPORTANT?
SO THIS YEAR, EVERY HASBRO TOY
DONATED TO TOYS FOR TOTS
WILL BE POWERED BY DURACELL.
HAPPY HOLIDAYS.
DURACELL WITH DURALOCK.
TRUSTED EVERYWHERE.
WE ASSOCIATE ALL KINDS
OF CREATURES
WITH THE HOLIDAY SEASON--
REINDEER, OF COURSE.
PARTRIDGES IN PEAR TREES.
CATS. WELL, ALL RIGHT.
MAYBE NOT CATS YET,
BUT AFTER THIS, OH, YOU WILL.
HEY, I THOUGHT ONLY REINDEER
FLEW AT CHRISTMAS.
(bang)
(woman) OH!
(child laughs)
OOH.
(man) PUT HIM ON THE GROUND.
NO, WE'RE NOT MAKING HIM
DO THIS.
JUST SEE IF HE CAN WALK.
HE CAN'T WALK, ROB.
KIDS AREN'T THE ONLY ONES
WHO HATE CLOTHES FOR CHRISTMAS.
NO, ROB, THIS IS CRUEL.
COME ON.
HONEY, PUT HIM ON HIS FEET.
LET HIM CRAWL.
HE...
(laughs)
ROB, NO.
COME HERE.
FRED... (laughs)
(laughter)
ROB, THIS IS MEAN.
COME ON. (laughs)
FRED. (makes kissing sounds)
FRED.
(laughter)
(indistinct conversations)
APPARENTLY, CURIOSITY
WRAPPED THE CAT.
LOOK. LOOK.
(laughter continues)
(woman) OPEN IT.
(laughs)
YOU KNOW
THE TEN LORDS-A-LEAPIN'?
THIS MUST BE THEIR CAT.
OH!
(man's voice)
♪ OH, CHRISTMAS TREE
♪ HOW LOVELY
ARE YOUR BRACHES ♪
(Tom, singsongy)
THIS IS WHAT YOU GET
FOR PEEKING IN YOUR STOCKING
BEFORE CHRISTMAS.
(laughter)
(woman) ALL RIGHT, GO AHEAD.
OPEN IT. HURRY UP.
WHY? IS IT GONNA SUFFOCATE
OR SOMETHING?
RIP IT FROM THE TOP.
AAH! OH, MY. OH, MY!
OH! OH!
(laughs)
OH, MY GOD. AM I REALLY SEEING
SOMETHING WITH MY EYES?
OH, MY GOD! OH, MY!
COME TO MA--
OH, MY! OH! OH!
IS THIS A DREAM OR SOMETHING?
(laughing)
OH, MY! OH, MY GOD!
OH, MY GOD! OH!
I PULLED A MUSCLE.
AND NOW...
WHAT ARE THEY?
(whirring)
(man) ALL DONE.
NOW GO GET PRESENTS.
WHAT ARE THEY?
(speaks indistinctly)
(crash)
WELL, SO MUCH
FOR THAT PRESENT.
(crying)
THIS HAS BEEN...
I BET SANTA AND MRS. CLAUS
HAVE A REALLY GOOD MARRIAGE.
I'M SURE THEY DO,
BUT YOU CAN HARDLY BLAME HER
IF OCCASIONALLY SHE GOT
ON THE BIG GUY'S CASE.
"REALLY? YOU GOTTA WORK
ON CHRISTMAS... AGAIN?"
HE'S GOT THE REMOTE CONTROL,
BUT WHERE'S THE REST
OF HIS GIFT?
(man) I DON'T KNOW.
YOU'LL HAVE TO TURN IT ON.
I DON'T REMEMBER.
(whirring)
(woman laughing)
(boy) OHH.
HEY, SANTA, NEXT TIME
YOU CATCH BIG AIR,
USE YOUR REINDEER.
OW! AAH!
YOU ALL RIGHT, SANTA?
(grunting)
WHY SHOULD THE TREE BE
THE ONLY ONE
WITH THAT FRESH PINE SCENT?
(woman) OH, MY GOSH!
(laughs)
OH, MY GOSH!
HELP IT OFF OF HER!
HELP IT OFF!
OH, MY GOSH.
OHH!
(laughter)
ARE YOU...
OH, MY GOD!
(whispering indistinctly)
(woman laughing)
(woman) NO, I DIDN'T BUY IT.
THERE'S ANOTHER TREBLE CLEF
UP THERE, BUT I...
YOU KNOW WHAT SHE WANTS
FOR CHRISTMAS?
A CONCERNED HUSBAND.
RIGHT HERE'S A LITTLE...
WHOA! WHOA!
OH, JEEZ!
(woman)
PUT HIM ON HIS BACK, HONEY,
BECAUSE I DON'T WANT HIS FACE
TO--
HE'S GONNA... HE'S GONNA...
HERE'S A KID WHO NEEDS
SOME CLOTHES FOR CHRISTMAS.
AND THEN GET DRESSED
FOR BED.
(man laughing)
(woman screaming and laughing)
(speaks indistinctly)
HERE, HERE, HERE,
HERE, HERE.
I'M READY TO OPEN SOMETHIN'.
(passes gas)
(woman) JIMMY!
EXCUSE ME.
(laughs)
DID YOU FEEL THAT?
(hooves clomping)
WELL, I THINK YOU CAN SEE WHY
HOLIDAYS
AT THE DISNEYLAND RESORT
HAVE BECOME A TRADITION
FOR SO MANY FAMILIES.
IT'S THE PERFECT TIME
TO SHARE MEMORABLE MOMENTS
YOU'LL TREASURE FOREVER.
NOW TO HELP ME WISH YOU
A MERRY CHRISTMAS--
IN ADDITION
TO OUR SPECIAL GUEST,
THE BIG GUY,
SANTA CLAUS HIMSELF,
WE'VE GOT FOUR
OF OUR VERY BEST FRIENDS.
LET'S HEAR IT FOR MICKEY,
DONALD, GOOFY, AND PLUTO!
GOOD NIGHT, MICKEY.
THANKS SO MUCH
FOR HAVING US HERE.
AND THANKS FOR BEING WITH US
TO YOU, TOO, AT HOME.
GOOD NIGHT, EVERYBODY.
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
-- Captions by VITAC --
THAT'S A "BYE."
ALL RIGHT! NICELY DONE.
(John H.)
HO HO HO, AMERICA!
"WIPEOUT'S" BACK,
AND IT'S TIME TO DECK THE BALL.
'TIS THE SEASON TO BE BALLSY!
(John A.) THAT'S RIGHT.
THE WORLD'S MOST EXTRAORDINARY
OBSTACLE COURSE
IS RINGING IN WINTER WITH
A VERY SPECIAL HOLIDAY EDITION.
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
OUR BALLS HAVE BEEN DECKED,
AND 24 MERRYMAKERS ARE READY
TO BATTLE IT OUT FOR $50,000.
WE'LL SEE
WHO'S NAUGHTY OR NICE...
OHH!
RING SOME BELLS...
UHH!
AND SPREAD CHRISTMAS CHEER
ALL OVER THE COURSE.
ONLY THREE WILL ADVANCE
TO FACE THE BITTER COLD
IN THE ALL-NEW
WINTER WIPEOUT ZONE.
THE HOLIDAYS' MOST EPIC
COMPETITION BEGINS NOW.
ONE WILL BECOME A CHAMPION,
BUT ALL WILL...
WIPE OUT.
(woman) I LOVE YOU, CHRISTMAS!