BUT YOUR DORM ROOM
IS ONLY SO BIG.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO LEAVE
SOME OF THIS STUFF BEHIND.
(Martha) DON'T LISTEN TO HIM,
DARLING.
EVERYBODY NEEDS THEIR STUFF.
SEE?
(Martha sighs)
MY LITTLE GIRL
IS GOING TO COLLEGE.
SEEMS LIKE JUST YESTERDAY,
YOU WERE CHECKING UNDER
THE BED EVERY NIGHT,
PROMISING HER
THAT MONSTERS AREN'T REAL.
WELL, I LIED.
MONSTERS ARE REAL.
THEY'RE THE BOYS
IN HER FRESHMAN DORM.
OH, SPEAKING OF WHICH,
BEFORE ALEXIS LEAVES, DON'T YOU
THINK YOU SHOULD HAVE THE, UH,
TALK WITH HER?
YOU MEAN THE SEX TALK? MOTHER,
I COVERED THAT AGES AGO.
I LEARNED SO MUCH.
I MEAN THE YOU-AND-BECKETT
SEX TALK.
MOTHER, BECKETT AND I AR--
SAVE IT, RICHARD.
I KNEW THE MORNING
I WALKED IN HERE
AND THE POOR GIRL
WAS HIDING IN THE--
YOU--
SHH.
(lowered voice)
HOW DID YOU KNOW THAT?
SHH, SHH, SHH.
(lowered voice)
MOTHERS KNOW THESE THINGS.
BUT I DON'T THINK YOU WANT
ALEXIS TO WALK IN UNANNOUNCED
AND FIND YOU AND BECKETT...
OUT OF THE CLOSET.
AND BY "OUT OF THE CLOSET"--
I--NO, I-I-I KNOW WHAT YOU MEAN
BY "OUT OF THE CLOSET."
OKAY, SO...
DON'T YOU THINK
YOU SHOULD TELL HER?
TELL ME WHAT?
(Beckett)
YOU TOLD ALEXIS?
I DIDN'T WANT TO. MOTHER USED
HER JEDI MIND TRICKS ON ME.
SHE KNOWS, TOO?
CASTLE, DO THEY REALIZE
WHAT'S AT STAKE HERE?
BECAUSE IF ALEXIS
TELLS LANIE...
ALEXIS WON'T TELL LANIE.
LANIE'S GONNA TELL ESPOSITO,
ESPOSITO CAN'T KEEP
HIS MOUTH SHUT WITH RYAN,
AND RYAN'S GONNA BLOW IT
OUT OF PROPORTION,
AND THEN GATES
IS GONNA FIND OUT,
AND WE WON'T BE ABLE
TO WORK TOGETHER ANYMORE.
TRUST ME.
SHE KNOWS WHAT'S AT STSTAKE,
AND OUR SECRET IS SAFE.
(people speaking indistinctly)
SO HOW DID SHE TAKE IT,
US BEING TOGETHER?
SHE WAS TOO PREOCCUPIED
WITH HER MOVE TO EVEN COMMENT.
I MEAN, IT'S RIDICULOUS.
SHE'S GOT BOXES AND BOXES
OF STUFF,
AND APPARENTLY,
ALL OF IT'S IMPORTANT.
YEAH, WELL, WE ALL NEED
OUR STUFF, CASTLE.
I'VE GOT BOXES
AND BOXES OF IT.
IT'S COMFORTING.
IT REMINDS ME OF MY PAST.
YOUR KINKY PAST?
I'VE GOT THAT BOX, TOO.
(siren wails)
(camera shutter clicking)
HOUSEKEEPING FOUND HER
THIS MORNING.
NAME'S WENDY DUPREE,
25 YEARS OF AGE,
SINGLE GUNSHOT TO THE CHEST
FROM A 9 MILLIMETER.
UNFORTUNATELY,
SHE DIED SLOWLY.
(Beckett) YEAH, LONG ENOUGH
TO WRITE THE WORD "LIE."
SO OUR KILLER WASN'T A PRO.
SHE WOULDN'T HAVE
BEEN LEFT BREATHING.
A DYING DECLARATION,
BUT WHAT DOES IT MEAN?
HEY,
THAT'S YOUR DEPARTMENT.
WELL, DID SOMEONE
LIE TO HER?
PERHAPS IT'S
THE KILLER'S INITIALS.
MM.
MAYBE A GRAMMATICAL ERROR.
SHE SHOULD'VE WRITTEN "LAY."
(Esposito) YO, BECKETT.
VICTIM'S WALLET.
(camera shutter clicks)
SHE CAME A LONG WAY
TO GET KILLED.
SHE'S A PHILLY GIRL.
HOW LONG
WAS SHE HERE FOR?
FRONT DESK SAYS SHE CHECKED IN
YESTERDAY AFTERNOON ALONE.
SHE WASN'T ALONE.
SHE BROUGHT 4,000
OF HER CLOSEST FRIENDS.
THAT KIND OF CASH, WHAT'S SHE
DOING IN A DUMP LIKE THIS?
ALL RIGHT, RUN FINANCIALS.
SEE WHAT YOU GUYS CAN FIND.
YEAH.
CASTLE, WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I THINK, AS MUCH AS I LOVE
A GOOD MYSTERY,
SHE COULD'VE LEFT
A MORE HELPFUL NOTE.
HERE'S A MESSAGE THAT NEEDS
NO INTERPRETATION.
"YOU THINK YOU CAN LIE TO ME?"
AH. MAYBE THAT'S THE LIE.
"RUN ALL YOU WANT. I'M GONNA
FIND YOU AND MAKE YOU PAY."
IT'S A 2-1-5 AREA CODE.
THAT'S PHILLY.
PULL A WARRANT
FOR THE CELL PHONE.
I WANT TO KNOW
WHO SENT THAT TEXT.
YEAH, I SENT IT.
YOU BET I DID.
WELL, IT SOUNDS LIKE YOU HAD
A BIG PROBLEM WITH HER.
HELL, YEAH, I HAD A PROBLEM.
WENDY'S A WAITRESS AT MY PLACE,
JOEL'S CHEESESTEAKS--
THE BEST IN PHILLY.
"THE BEST IN PHILLY"?
THAT'S A TAD PRESUMPTUOUS.
WELL, IT IS.
SO YESTERDAY I SENT
THAT FRAUL TO THE BANK
TO MAKE A DEPOSIT
FOR THE RESTAURANT, RIGHT?
BUT DOES SHEHE MAKE THDROP?
NO.
SHE HIGHTAILS IT UP HERE
WITH 4,000 OF MY DOLLARS.
THAT'S A LOT OF CHEESESTEAK.
SO YOU FOLLOWED HER TO NEW YORK
TO GET YOUR MONEY BACK.
DAMN RIGHT.
I TRIED TO BE NICE.
FINALLY, SHE CALLS ME,
AND SHE'S LIKE, "I'M SORRY.
IT WAS AN EMERGENCY.
I'LL PAY YOU BACK DOUBLE
WHEN I GET BACK."
SCREW THAT.
SHE STOLE FROM ME.
AND FOR THAT,
SHE DESERVED TO DIE?
YEAH.
WAIT. WHAT?
OH, NO.
NO.
I DIDN'T DO THIS.
NAH. I COULDN'T EVEN
FIND HER.
NO, I-I JUST GOT OFF
THE TRAIN FROM PHILLY, UH,
AN HOUR BEFORE YOUS GUYS
PICKED ME UP.
SO AMTRAK CONFIRMS THAT PRATT
WAS TICKETED YESTERDAY,
BUT THEY CAN'T BE SURE
OF WHAT TRAIN HE WAS ON.
SO WE'RE DOUBLE-CHECKING
HIS ALIBI.
HAVE THEM CHECK ON
THAT CHEESESTEAK, TOO.
THERE'S NO WAY THAT IT'S
THE BEST IN PHILLY.
ANYWAY, EVEN IF IT WAS HIM,
IT DOESN'T EXPLAIN WENDY'S
MYSTERIOUS EMERGENCY--
THE STOLEN CASH,
THE SUDDEN TRIP
TO NEW YORK CITY.
MM. WHY SHE WOULD WRITE "LIE."
YOU DON'T WRITE A DYING MESSAGE
IN BLOOD JUST FOR KICKS.
THERE HAD TO BE A REASON.
ARE YOU OUT, TOO?
WANT SOME MORE?
YEAH. UH, YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'LL GO GET IT.
OH.
THANK YOU.
MM-HMM.
(people speaking indistinctly)
LONG ISLAND EXPRESSWAY.
LITERARY INSTITUTE
OF EXCELLENCE.
LOVE IS EVERYTHING.
OH, DID I JUST SAY THAT?
(telephone rings)
I'M GETTING SOFT.
(ring)
DETECTIVE BECKETT'S PHONE.
CASTLE?
YOU'RE NOT ALLOWED TO ANSWER
BECKETT'S PHONE.
YES, I AM.
SINCE WHEN?
SINCE I...
CAN--IS THERE SOMETHING
I CAN DO FOR YOU?
Yeah.
Write this down.
I'VE GOT A PARTIAL
OFF THE SHELL CASING.
NO MATCHES IN THE SYSTEM
or to Mr. Pratt,
BUT I DID FIND
SOME TRACE D.N.A.
Are you writing this down?
YES.
CASTLE.
OKAY, HANG ON.
(laughs)
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
Ooh.
YOU ARE IN TROUBLE.
I'M NOT IN TROUBLE.
LANIE GOT A PARTIAL PRINT.
IT IS NOT A MATCH FOR PRATT.
HE IS NOT OUR GUY.
WHO SAID THAT YOU COULD
ANSWER MY PHONE?
AND WHY ARE YOU
GOING THROUGH MY DRAWERS?
I WAS JUST LOOKING
FOR A PAD OF PAPER.
SURE YOU WERE.
STAY OUT OF MY STUFF, CASTLE.
YOUR STUFF?
(closes drawer)
NEED I REMIND YOU,
I'VE ALREADY SEEN
YOUR STUFF.
YEAH, WELL, SOME OF MY STUFF
IS STILL PRIVATE.
OH, I GET IT.
AN OLD BOYFRIEND
MADE THAT FOR YOU.
NO.
REALLY?
'CAUSE IT'S TOTALLY COOL.
I WOULDN'T BE JEALOUS.
OKAY,
MAYBE A LITTLE BIT JEALOUS.
NOT AN OLD BOYFRIEND?
MNH-MNH.
YOU GOT IT FROM A CRIME SCENE.
THAT IS A KEEPSAKE
FROM THE FIRST MURDERER
YOU EVER COLLARED.
I TOLD YOU, CASTLE,
IT'S PRIVATE.
MAYBE IT'S
THE ACTUAL MURDER VICTIM
FROM A STICK MAN CONVENTION.
REALLY?
THAT'S THE BEST
THAT YOU CAN COME UP WITH?
CHALLENGE ACCEPTED.
(Ryan) SO...
NOTHING IN THE FINANCIALS
EXPLAIN WHY WENDY NEEDED
4 GRAND IN CASH,
BUT I MIGHT HAVE FIGURED OUT
WHAT SHE WAS DOING IN TOWN.
SHE USED HER CREDIT CARD
FOR A CAB RIDE
TO 8th AND MARKET YESTERDAY.
THE DAY SHE WAS KILLED.
I SPOKE WITH A CABBIE.
WENDY TOOK HIS BUSINESS CARD.
SAID SHE WAS GOING TO CALL
TO HAVE HIM
TAKE HER BACK THERE TODAY.
BET WE FIND OUR ANSWER THERE.
A SELF-STORAGE WAREHOUSE?
WHAT'S A GIRL FROM PHILLY
DOING IN A PLACE LIKE THIS?
(woman) OH, YEAH, YEAH.
SHE WAS HERE.
A LOT LESS BLOODY
WHEN I SAW HER, THOUGH.
SHE SIGNED UP FOR THE AUCTION.
AUCTION?
EVERY MONTH WE AUCTION OFF
REPOSSESSED STORAGE UNITS.
YOU KNOW, FROM DEADBEATS
THAT DON'T PAY THEIR BILLS.
THERE'S ONE GOING ON
RIGHT NOW.
THAT'S WHAT THE $4,000
WAS FOR.
SHE WAS GONNA BID ON A UNIT.
WHICH UNIT?
BEATS ME.
COULD BE ANY ONE OF THE 14
WE GOT UP FOR BID.
SO THERE'S NO WAY OF TELLING
WHICH ONE SHE WAS INTERESTED IN?
ACTUALLY, THERE IS A WAY.
WE MISINTERPRETED
WENDY'S MESSAGE.
IT'S NOT "LIE."
WE WERE LOOKING AT IT
UPSIDE DOWN.
IT'S "3-1-7." THAT'S WHAT
SHE WAS TRYING TO SAY.
IS UNIT 317 UP FOR AUCTION?
OH, AS A MATTER OF FACT,
IT IS.
PROBABLY AUCTIONING IT OFF
AS WE SPEAK.
WENDY WAS KILLED TRYING
TO BUY THAT UNIT.
IF WE LET IT GET SOLD OFF...
THEN WE'LL LOSE OUR BEST SHOT AT
FINDING OUT WHO THE KILLER IS.
Captioning provided by
ABC Studios, ABC, Inc.
and brought to you by Ford.
Go Further.
[Music:
Artist: Willy Moon
♪ Everybody well don't
you know it's me now? ♪
♪ Yeah who's it,
who's it huh? ♪
♪ Willy's back with a
brand new beat now, ♪
♪ Yeah doin' it doin' it up!
♪ Heyyy yeah, tryin'
to bite my style! ♪
♪ Heyyy yeah, how you
like me now? ♪
♪ Na na na na na na na na
♪ And everybody go uh!
♪
How advanced is the
new Ford Fusion?
Well...it has outstanding
performance and handling...
...and it offers a plug-in
hybrid
that gets a projected 100 MPGe.
Of course, there's still
one thing it can't do.
Introducing the entirely
new Ford Fusion.
It's an entirely new idea of
what a car can be.
NESPRESSO.
WHERE I NEVER HAVE TO COMPROMISE
ON ANYTHING.
♪
WHERE JUST ONE TOUCH
CREATES THE PERFECT COFFEE.
WHERE EVERY CAPPUCCINO AND LATTE
IS ONLY MADE WITH FRESH MILK.
AND WHERE THE STAFF
IS EXCEPTIONALLY FRIENDLY.
♪
NESPRESSO. WHAT ELSE?
FAMILY PARTY IN FIFTEEN.
OK LET'S DO IT!
[ Female Announcer ] IT'S
THE HOLIDAY SALE AT PAYLESS.
GRAB ALL THE STYLES YOU NEED
IN A FLASH
AT FESTIVELY LOW PRICES.
RIGHT NOW AT PAYLESS.
Introducing NOOK HD -
the world's best 7" tablet made
for reading and entertainment.
Your favorite magazines and
catalogs look better than ever.
And with scrapbooking,
you can save the
things you love,
bring them all together,
And be inspired like
never before.
Scrapbooking. Create
yours with Nook HD -
and even bigger with HD+.
Find yours at Barnes & Noble.
(man)
OKAY, NEXT UP IS UNIT 317.
YOU HAVE 60 SECONDS TO LOOK,
AND THEN WE START THE BIDDING.
ALL RIGHT, RYAN, SO THE OWNER
OF THE UNIT WAS A JOHAN FLEMING.
CAN YOU RUN THAT?
(people speaking indistinctly)
OKAY, THANKS.
(cell phone beeps)
WE NEED YOU
TO STOP THIS AUCTION.
AS MUCH AS I'D LIKE TO HELP,
I'D LIKE MY MONEY MORE.
SO UNLESS YOU GOT A WARRANT,
I DON'T HAVE TO STOP JACK.
(man) OKAY, 30 SECONDS.
(Beckett) CASTLE,
WHAT DO YOU SEE?
UH... NOT MUCH.
JUST A...
JUST A BUNCH OF JUNK.
YEAH, WELL, THE KEY TO WENDY'S
MURDER MIGHT BE IN THAT JUNK,
AND WE'RE ABOUT TO LOSE IT.
THERE'S NO WAY I CAN GET
A WARRANT IN TIME.
YOU MAY NOT HAVE A WARRANT,
BUT I GOT SOMETHING BETTER.
CHECKBOOK.
(woman) AUCTIONS ARE CASH ONLY,
HOTSHOT.
OH, NO.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
IS 2 GRAND ENOUGH?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
WITH 2 GRAND IN YOUR POCKET?
I'M M A BEST-SLING AUTHOR.
WHY WOULDN'T I HAVE 2 GRAND
IN MY POCKET?
(man) ALL RIGHT.
WHAT DO YOU WANT TO GIVE FOR IT?
WHO'LL START US OUT?
$100 BID.
WHO'S GONNA GO $100
ONE TIME?
RIGHT HERE.
$100. NOW WHO'LL GO $200?
$200. $200 BID NOW.
YEP, YEP.
$200, THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
NOW WHO'S GONNA GO TO $300?
LOOKING FOR A $300 BID.
I GOT $300 ON IT.
BIG PERCY'S IN FOR $300.
NOW WHO WANTS TO GO $400?
RIGHT HERE.
WHO'S GOING $400? ONE TIME.
PRETTY BOY'S BACK,
AND HE'S IN FOR $400.
(whistles)
FRANKIE'S GOT $500.
NOW WHO'S GONNA GO $600?
$600--
YEP, YEP.
PEGGY'S IN FOR $600.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
NOW WHO'S GONNA GO $700?
$700--
NEXT 100.
$700. THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WHO'S GONNA GO $800?
WHO'S GOING $800 ONE TIME?
I GOT $800 ON IT.
BIG PERCY'S GOT $800.
NOW WHO'S GONNA GO $900?
(whistle)
FRANKIE'S GOT $900.
NOW LOOKING FOR A $1,000 BID.
WHO'S GOING $1,000 ONE TIME?
DO I HEAR $1,000
FROM ANYBODY HERE?
GO A $1,000 BID ONE TIME.
$1,500.
ANYBODY GONNA TOP THAT?
ANYBODY ANYWHERE?
$1,500 GOING ONCE.
$1,500 GOING TWICE.
(man) $1,600.
(auctioneer) SWEET 16
GETS IN JUST UNDER THE WIRE.
NOW WHO'S GONNA GO $1,700?
WANT TO GO $1,700 ONE TIME?
WANT TO GO $1,700?
LOOKING FOR A $1,700 BID.
ANYBODY FOR $1,700?
I'VE ONLY GOT $2,000.
(people speaking indistinctly)
HERE.
SIGN IT.
NOW KEEP BIDDING.
HI. HI.
BIG PERCY, RIGHT?
WHAT WOULD IT TAKE TO GET
ALL THE CASH YOU HAVE ON YOU?
DEPENDS ON WHAT YOU OFFERING.
HOW ABOUT A CHECK?
NO, IT'S GOOD. I SWEAR.
IT'S SIGNED BY THE MILLIONAIRE
MYSTERY NOVELIST RICHARD CASTLE.
YEAH, RIGHT.
NO, REALLY.
HE'S RIGHT BEHIND ME.
FOR REAL?
YEAH.
MY MOMS LOVES HIS BOOKS.
YES. I'LL DO IT.
OKAY.
I'LL GIVE YOU $1,600.
BUT IT'LL COST $2,500.
$1,800.
$2,300.
2 GRAND, AND HE'LL NAME
A CHARACTER IN HIS NEXT NOVEL
AFTER YOUR MOM.
WHAT?
SOLD.
HERE YOU GO. THANKS.
WE GOT $3,600.
NOW MAKE IT WORK.
WHO'LL GO TO 24 AND A HALF?
GIVE ME 24 AND A HALF ONE TIME.
WATCH THIS.
$2,500 ONE TIME.
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
GIVE ME $2,500.
DO I HEAR $2,500
ANYWHERE?
$3,000.
$3,000...
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
TRUST ME. I GOT THIS.
(auctioneer)
GO $3,100 ONE TIME.
I THINK HE MIGHT BUY IT.
WHO'LL GO $3,100?
$3,050.
NOW YOU WANT TO GO $3,100?
YOU GO $3,100 ONE TIME?
LET ME HEAR IT.
YOU WANT TO GO $3,100 ONE TIME?
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
$3,500.
NOW YOU WANT TO GO $3,600?
(lowered voice)
CASTLE, WE'VE ONLY GOT $3,600.
(auctioneer) GO 35 AND A HALF.
GO 35 AND A HALF.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I CAN DO THIS ALL DAY.
I'LL OUTBID MYSELF. $3,600.
(auctioneer) $3,600.
ANYBODY GONNA TOP THAT?
ANYBODY WHERE?
$3,600 GOING ONCE.
$3,600 GOING TWICE. BID NOW
OR FOREVER HOLD YOUR PEACE.
SOLD RIGHT THERE
TO PRETTY BOY FOR $3,600.
(woman) WHOO-HOO!
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
(indistinct conversations)
HOW DID YOU EVEN KNOW
THAT WAS GONNA WORK?
WELL, AS A CHAMPION
POKER PLAYER,
I AM A STUDENT
OF BODY LANGUAGE.
I COULD TELL EASILY
BY LOOKING AT HIM--
YOU HAD ABSOLUTELY NO IDEA.
NOT A CLUE.
CONGRATS.
ALL THAT JUNK IS YOURS.
YEAH, THANKS.
OH, AND, UH,
MY MOTHER'S NAME...
IS EUNICE.
EXCUSE ME.
EUNICE?
DAMN, BRO. YOU ACTUALLY
BOUGHT ALL THIS CRAP?
ALL THIS CRAP IS GONNA CRACK
THIS CASE WIDE OPEN.
THANK YOU, L.T.
YOU ARE SO GOING TO OWE ME
FOR THIS.
CASTLE, I DON'T KNOW
IF THE DEPARTMENT'S
GONNA BE ABLE TO REIMBURSE YOU
FOR ALL OF THIS.
(whispers) THAT'S NOT
THE OWING I MEAN.
RAN DOWN THE NAME
ON UNIT 317--
JOHAN FLEMING.
ADDRESS IS BOGUS.
NAME IS BOGUS.
THE GUY DOESN'T EXIST.
THEN WHOSE STUFF IS THIS?
WELL, THE ANSWER'S
RIGHT IN FRONT OF US.
HIS STUFF WILL TELL US
WHO HE IS.
LOOK, THERE'S A BOX OF MAPS.
UM, HE WAS A GEOGRAPHY BUFF.
HE ENJOYED TRAVEL.
MAYBE HE WAS A TRUCKER.
AH. SEE? PROGRESS.
OOH. YO, CLIMBING GEAR.
HE'S AN OUTDOORSMAN.
A SUPER CREEPY OUTDOORSMAN.
EW.
HEY, THIS IS HIGH-END STUFF,
CASTLE.
CAN I HAVE THIS?
NO.
WHY NOT?
YOU'RE NOT A CLIMBER.
I SPENT A LOT OF MONEY
ON THIS STUFF.
YOU WANT SOMETHING?
MAKE ME AN OFFER.
(Gates) WHAT THE HELL
IS GOING ON HERE?
WHOSE JUNK IS THIS,
AND WHAT IN THE HELL IS
IT DOING IN MY PRECINCT?
IT'S CASTLE'S, SIR.
MR. CASTLE.
UH, SIR, ACTUALLY,
IT'S A PART OF
AN ONGOING INVESTIGATION.
I DON'T CARE.
I WANT IT GONE, ALL OF IT.
(people speaking indistinctly)
IS THAT...
OH, IT IS.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT YOU HAVE?
HOW RARE THAT PIECE IS?
(Beckett) SIR?
ARE YOU A COLLECTOR?
EVER SINCE I WAS A KID.
I HAVE SEARCHED...
FOR YEARS.
WELL...
SEARCH NO MORE.
NO.
YES.
IT'S YOURS.
REALLY? WELL, I--
I DON'T KNOW W--I--
SAY YOU'LL ACCEPT.
OH.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
UH... CARRY ON.
OH, YOU CAN GIVE HER SOMETHING,
BUT YOU CAN'T GIVE ME SOMETHING?
YEAH, YOU ALREADY LIKE ME.
HEY, GUYS. MOTHER LODE.
TAX RETURNS.
LOOKS LIKE JOHAN FLEMING'S
ACTUALLY WENDELL DUPREE.
THAT'S THE SAME LAST NAME
AS OUR VICTIM.
YES, AND THE SAME DATE OF BIRTH,
TOO. THEY MUST BE TWINS.
WAIT. TWINS.
(snaps fingers)
OF COURSE.
IT ALL MAKES SENSE NOW.
WENDELL'S SECRET IDENTITY--
JOHAN FLEMING--
IS THE SAME SECRET IDENTITY
OF ZAN,
THE MALE HALF
OF THE WONDER TWINS.
WONDER TWINS?
THE "SUPER FRIENDS"?
SERIOUSLY, YOU GUYS,
DO YOU NOT WATCH TV?
IF THIS UNIT BELONGED
TO HER BROTHER,
THEN WHY
WAS WENDY BIDDING ON IT?
WHY DID HE STOP MAKING PAYMENTS?
AND WHY WAS HE USING AN ALIAS?
WHY DON'T WE TRACK DOWN WENDELL
AND ASK HIM?
(under breath)
WHY DON'T YOU BUY A TV?
WHO KNEW THAT GATES HAD
A SOFTER SIDE?
(speaks indistinctly)
(normal voice) OH, GOD.
JUST BEAUTIFUL.
IT'S, UM...
CREEPY, VERY, VERY...
CREEPY.
SO WHERE ARE WE
ON THE BROTHER?
OH, IT TURNS OUT THE TWINS
HAD A HARD KNOCK LIFE.
THEIR PARENTS DIED
IN A CAR CRASH
WHEN THEY WERE TEENS.
IT'S LIKE WENDELL
NEVER REALLY FULLY RECOVERED.
HE MOVED FROM TOWN TO TOWN,
GETTING IN SCRAPES WITH THE LAW.
SO WHERE CAN WE FIND HIM?
IN AN URN.
HE DIED SIX WEEKS AGO.
HIT BY A SUBWAY TRAIN.
OUCH.
EXPLAINS WHY HIS STORAGE BILL
WASN'T PAID.
IT SAYS HERE
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT?
WELL, THE SUBWAY CAMERAS
WERE BROKEN,
SO THERE'S REALLY NO WAY
TO KNOW FOR SURE.
IF HIS DEATH
IS RELATED TO WENDY'S,
WE COULD BE LOOKING
AT A SECOND MURDER.
(sighs) OKAY, SO THAT WAS
ONE OF WENDY'S
FELLOW WAITRESSES FROM PHILLY.
ACCORDING TO HER,
WENDY WAS CONVINCED
THAT HER BROTHER'S DEATH
WASN'T AN ACCIDENT.
APPARENTLY, HE WAS INVOLVED
IN SOMETHING DANGEROUS.
WHAT KIND OF DANGEROUS?
WENDY DIDN'T SAY,
BUT ACCORDING TO THIS WAITRESS,
JUST BEFORE THE SUBWAY ACCIDENT,
WENDELL CALLED HIS SISTER
AND SAID IT WAS OVER AND ALL
OF THEIR PROBLEMS WERE SOLVED.
(Esposito)
AND YET, HE ENDS UP DEAD
AND SHE WAS DESPERATE ENOUGH
TO RISK EVERYTHING--
HER JOB, JAIL--
JUST TO GO AFTER
HER BROTHER'S STORAGE UNIT.
WHY?
I MEAN, WE'VE BEEN THROUGH
ALL THIS STUFF.
IT JUST SEEMS LIKE
A BUNCH OF RANDOM JUNK.
WELL, MAYBE IT'S JUST THAT
WE DON'T KNOW EXACTLY
WHAT WE'RE LOOKING FOR.
I MEAN, WHOEVER KILLED WENDY
MOST LIKELY CAME
FROM WENDELL'S WORLD.
SO WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT HIM?
FOR THE LAST THREE MONTHS,
USING HIS WONDER TWIN ALIAS,
WENDELL WORKED AS A CHAUFFER
FOR ONE ANGELICA HENLEY,
A WEALTHY SOCIALITE.
OKAY.
THEN LET'S START HERE.
(light jazz music playing)
(indistinct conversations)
GOOD EVENING.
MAY I HELP YOU?
UH, WE WERE HOPING TO SPEAK
WITH MS. HENLEY.
THE LADY IN THE PURPLE
COCKTAIL DRESS.
MAY I TAKE YOU TO HER?
UH, YOU KNOW WHAT?
I THINK WE CAN MANAGE.
CHAMPAGNE?
I'M ON DUTY.
AH, ALAS, I'M FORCED
TO DRINK ALONE.
ANGELICA HENLEY.
ANHELICA.
THE "G" IS SILENT.
WOULDN'T THAT MAKE IT
ANELICA?
ANHELICA.
WELL,
I'M DETECTIVE KATE BECKETT,
AND THIS IS MR. CASTLE.
COULD WE HAVE A WORD?
WHAT'S ALL THIS ABOUT?
I HAVE GUESTS.
NOW I UNDERSTAND
THAT YOU EMPLOYED A MAN
NAMED JOHAN FLEMING.
YES, AND I WAS SO HEARTBROKEN
WHEN THE POOR BOY DIED.
WELL, WERE YOU AWARE THAT HIS
REAL NAME WAS WENDELL DUPREE?
NO, I WASN'T.
DID HE HAVE ANY ENEMIES?
NO, I-I DON'T THINK SO.
WAIT. YOU MEAN, HIS--
HIS NAME WAS WENDELL?
WAS HE IN TROUBLE?
WAS HE INVOLVED
IN ANY ILLEGAL ACTIVITIES.
NO, NO, NO.
THE POLICE CLEARED HIM.
OF WHAT?
OH, WELL, TWO DAYS BEFORE
HE DIED, I WAS ROBBED.
SOMEBODY BROKE IN HERE
AND CRACKED MY WALL SAFE.
WHAT DID THEY TAKE?
MY BRACELET MADE OUT OF
PINK DIAMONDS
THAT WAS WORTH
OVER $4 MILLION.
WENDELL STOLE THE BRACELET.
(Beckett) THAT'S WHAT'S
IN THE STORAGE UNIT.
THAT'S WHY HE WAS KILLED.
He is a good little monkey
and always very curious.
One day George got an important
letter...
He's built a rocket ship to
travel into space.
It's just the right size for a
clever monkey.
Do you want to go into space,
George?
You will have to be very brave.
Hi, Grandma!
Oh hi,. my little monkey!
Here.
Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
Everyone got on and they were
off to the launching site.
Google, how far is Earth to the
Moon?
Moon is 238,900 miles...
The great moment had come...
...5...4...3...2...1
Even though our mom tries,
she doesn't really get us.
And she'll never know
who we are, or what...
No way,
Madden Girls??
Nike!
They're so awesome!
Wow!
Yeahhhh!
Thank you!
Who's your mommy now?
It's a
Christmas miracle.
Give Victoriously.
Famous brands. Famously easy.
Famous Footwear.
Victory is Yours.
YEAH WE BOTH RELIEVE COUGHS,
SNEEZING,
ACHES, FEVERS.
AND I RELIEVE
NASAL CONGESTION.
OVERACHIEVER.
[ Female Announcer ] TYLENOL®
COLD MULTI-SYMPTOM NIGHTTIME
RELIEVES NASAL CONGESTION.
NYQUIL® COLD AND FLU DOESN'T.
OH. WHOA-HO.
WHOOP.
WHOO.
(sighs) WHAT ARE YOU
SO HAPPY ABOUT?
THERE IS A $4-MILLION
DIAMOND BRACELET
BURIED IN MY AUCTION WINNINGS.
I'M RICH.
OR RICHER.
TILL DETECTIVE BECKETT
TAKES IT FROM YOU
AND RETURNS IT
TO ITS RIGHTFUL OWNER.
YES, BUT NOT EVEN THAT
CAN RUIN MY DAY
BECAUSE TONIGHT
IS MY VERY SPECIAL
LAST-NIGHT-BEFORE-COLLEGE
DINNER WITH MY DAUGHTER.
ABOUT THAT.
CAN WE CANCEL?
WHAT? WHOA. WHAT? WHY?
ALEXIS, WE MADE THESE PLANS
MONTHS AGO.
DO YOU KNOW HOW HARD IT IS, EVEN
FOR ME, TO GET RESERVATIONS--
IF IT'S THE RESERVATIONS
YOU CARE SO MUCH ABOUT,
WHY DON'T YOU JUST TAKE
YOUR GIRLFRIEND?
HOLD ON, ALEXIS.
THAT'S NOT...
THAT'S NOT--
(door slams)
THAT'S NOT WHAT I MEANT.
ALEXIS HATES ME?
IS IT
BECAUSE WE'RE TOGETHER?
I GUESS SHE FEELS LIKE
SHE'S BEING REPLACED,
WHICH IS WEIRD
BECAUSE SHE'S NEVER
DONE THIS BEFORE--
NOT WITH GINA,
NOT WITH THE HUNDREDS OF
SUPER-HOT GIRLFRIENDS I'VE--
OKAY, I DON'T NEED
TO HEAR THIS.
(whispers) RIGHT.
SO DO YOU THINK I SHOULD
TALK TO HER?
NO, NO, NO, NO.
NO, SHE'LL EAT YOU ALIVE.
LET ME HANDLE IT.
HANDLE WHAT?
(Castle and Beckett)
NOTHING.
SO... UNIFORMS ARE GOING
THROUGH WENDELL'S BELONGINGS,
LOOKING FOR THE BRACELET,
BUT ROBBERY FINALLY SENT OVER
THE REPORT
ON THE BREAK-IN
ON ANGELICA HENLEY'S.
TAKE A LOOK AT THESE.
WOW. A REAL BEAUTY.
CERTAINLY WORTH KILLING FOR.
I AM SPEAKING OF THE BRACELET
IN CASE ANYONE IS WONDERING.
IT WAS A 2-MAN JOB,
PRETTY SOPHISTICATED, TOO.
ONE SUSPECT PUT A BYPASS
ON THE ALARM IN THE BASEMENT.
THE OTHER
RAPPELLED FROM THE ROOF
AND WENT IN THROUGH THE WINDOW.
WHICH EXPLAINS THE CLIMBING
EQUIPMENT YOU HAD YOUR EYE ON.
(Beckett) SO WENDELL
WAS SUSPICIOUSLY HIT BY A TRAIN
AFTER STEALING
A DIAMOND BRACELET,
AND THEN SIX WEEKS LATER,
HIS SISTER GOES LOOKING
FOR HIS STORAGE UNIT,
AND SHE ENDS UP DEAD.
WHAT IF IT'S A "NO HONOR
AMONG THIEVES" THING?
YOU SAID IT WAS A 2-MAN JOB.
WHAT IF
WENDELL'S PARTNER DECIDED
THAT HE WANTED THE BRACELET
FOR HIMSELF,
ONLY HE KILLED WENDELL
BEFORE HE FIGURED OUT
WHERE HE'D STASHED IT?
SO HE FOLLOWS WENDY, SHE LEADS
HIM TO THE STORAGE UNIT,
AND THEN HE KILLS HER.
FIND THE PARTNER,
FIND THE KILLER.
WELL, MAYBE WE ALREADY
FOUND HIM.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
CASTLE, DO YOU REMEMBER
AT THE AUCTION,
ALL OF THE BIDDERS
DROPPED OUT AFTER $1,500?
EXCEPT ONE.
HE KNEW WHAT WAS INSIDE.
WHY ELSE WOULD HE BID
SO HIGH?
(knock on door)
(Beckett)
FELIX GOZARIAN, NYPD.
OPEN UP.
JUST A SECOND!
(objects clatter)
HE'S MAKING A RUN FOR IT.
YEAH. GO. NYPD!
NYPD!
(clattering)
(grunts)
DON'T MOVE.
DROP IT.
(clatters)
I THOUGHT YOU WERE THIEVES
TRYING TO STEAL MY STUFF.
I HAD ABSOLUTELY NO IDEA WHAT
WAS IN THE STORAGE UNIT. IT'S--
YET,
UNLIKE ANYONE ELSE THERE,
YOU BID US THROUGH THE ROOF.
LADY, THAT'S STRATEGY.
I-I BID ON A LOT OF THINGS.
THAT'S HOW I MAKE MY MONEY.
SO YOU ACTUALLY...
SELL THIS STUFF?
NOT YET.
I'M STILL ORGANIZING,
CATALOGING.
THERE'S A METHOD
TO ALL OF THIS--
YOU KNOW, WHAT I COLLECT,
WHAT I BID ON.
ESPECIALLY WHEN YOU GOT
INSIDE INFORMATION.
YOU KNEW EXACTLY
WHAT WAS IN THAT UNIT.
NO, I DIDN'T.
YEAH, YOU KNOW,
I WAS THINKING,
WHEN I SIGNED UP
FOR THE AUCTION,
THERE WAS A GUY.
YEAH, OFFERED ME $500
TO BE HIS PROXY,
GET UNIT 317.
VERY SPECIFIC. 317.
AND WHAT DID YOU SAY?
(chuckles) I SAID NO.
$500? I'M NOT IN
FOR THE SHORT MONEY.
IT MADE ME CURIOUS.
317. WHY?
THAT WAS PROBABLY
WENDELL'S PARTNER.
MM-HMM.
AND WAS HE AT THE AUCTION?
NO. NO, NO, NO, NO.
I NEVER SAW HIM AGAIN.
WE'RE GONNA NEED YOU TO SIT
WITH A SKETCH ARTIST.
SO FELIX ALIBIED OUT.
BUT...
WHO'S THAT?
WENDELL'S PARTNER.
RYAN AND ESPOSITO ARE TRYING
TO I.D. HIM NOW.
HOW ABOUT YOU?
I HAVE RIPPED THROUGH
EVERYTHING IN THIS ROOM
BIG ENOUGH TO HIDE A BRACELET.
YOU YOOW WHAT I FOUND?
NOTHING?
ABSOLUTELY NOTHING.
SAVE FOR THESE
WICKED NUNCHAKUS,
WHICH IS HOW I BROKE
THE HOT DOG MAKER.
ALSO SOME NOTABLE BOOKS--
SLOVAKIAN POLKA MUSIC,
PROSTHETIC EYE MANUFACTURING,
AND MY FAVORITE,
A "HISTORY
OF IRISH TRAVELERS."
I DON'T GET IT.
ALL OF THE EVIDENCE,
WENDY'S MURDER--
EVERYTHING POINTS
TO THE FACT THAT
THAT BRACELET SHOULD BE
IN THERE.
WELL, IT'S NOT.
I DID, HOWEVER,
MAKE SOME HEADWAY
ON MY
LITTLE STICK MAN THEORY.
REALLY?
YES. WHILST YOU WERE STILL
AN OFFICER,
YOU RISKED YOUR LIFE
RUNNING INTO TRAFFIC
TO SAVE AN OLD GYPSY WOMAN.
A GYPSY WOMAN?
AN OLD GYPSY WOMAN.
TO REWARD YOUR BRAVERY,
SHE GAVE YOU A TALISMAN.
MM-HMM.
SHE SAID,
AS LONG AS YOU KEEP IT.
NO HARM WILL EVER BEFALL YOU.
NO HARM WILL EVER BEFALL ME?
YOU LOOK ALL RIGHT TO ME.
(Gates) SO, MR. CASTLE,
I DECIDED TO GIVE
"FROZEN HEAT" A READ,
AND YOU KNOW WHAT?
IT'S REALLY A GOOD BOOK.
YOU LIKED IT?
I LOVED IT.
I, UH, DO YOU MIND?
NO.
I-I ORDERED THE REST
OF THE NIKKI HEAT SERIES.
(chuckles)
(laughs)
AND, AGAIN, THANK YOU
FOR MY GEMINI COLLECTIBLE.
I NOW HAVE A COMPLETE SET.
YOU SEE THAT?
SHE LOVES ME NOW,
AND I'VE GOT THAT SCARY LITTLE
MONSTROSITY TO THANK FOR IT.
HEY, GUYS.
YOU NEED TO SEE THIS.
SO ROBBERY INTERVIEWED A GUY
NAMED MARCO VINSTROLLI.
(beeps)
HIS VAN GOT A PARKING TICKET
AROUND THE CORNER
THE NIGHT THAT
ANGELICA'S BRACELET WAS STOLEN.
NOW THEY FOUND NOTHING
TO CONNECT HIM, BUT...
(beep)
LOOK FAMILIAR?
THAT'S OUR GUY.
THE STORAGE MANAGER SAID
THAT HE RENTED MARCO A UNIT
ON THE SAME FLOOR
THE DAY BEFORE THE AUCTION.
SO I-I REVIEWED
THEIR SURVEILLANCE TAPES.
THIS IS FROM 6:00 A.M.
YESTERDAY MORNING.
FIVE HOURS BEFORE
THE AUCTION.
HE BROKE INTO MY STORAGE UNIT.
WELL, IT'S--IT WAS WENDELL'S
AT THE TIME,
BUT NOW IT'S MINE.
IS THAT A SAFE?
THAT'S WHY WE COULDN'T
FIND YOUR BRACELET.
(beep)
BECAUSE IT WASAS IN THE FE.
MY SAFE.
SO DO WE HAVE A LICENSE
ON THAT VAN?
(tires squeal)
(whirring)
PUT IT DOWN, DIRTBAG!
NYPD, PUT UP YOUR HANDS
RIGHT NOW!
TAKE YOUR HAND
OFF YOUR TOOL, MARCO.
(thuds, whirring stops)
(both snicker)
SHUT UP.
YEAH, YOU CAN ALSO GET VERIZON'S
SHARE EVERYTHING PLAN.
UNLIMITED TALK, TEXT
AND SHAREABLE DATA,
ON UP TO 10 DEVICES.
AWESOME, BECAUSE WE'VE GOT,
LIKE, TEN KIDS.
WOW!
WE HAVE THREE CHILDREN.
NOT IF YOU COUNT HOW MUCH
THEY TALK AND TEXT.
[ text alert ]
THEY'RE ALWAYS
TEXTING...
HA!
L-O...L.
U R CRAZY!
[ Male Announcer ] GET THE
SEASON'S HOTTEST SMARTPHONES,
LIKE THE DROID RAZR M
BY MOTOROLA.
WITH VERIZON'S
SHARE EVERYTHING PLAN.
AND USE YOUR SMARTPHONE AS
A HOTSPOT AT NO EXTRA CHARGE.
FROM AMERICA'S
GIFT HEADQUARTERS. WALMART.
A HOTSPOT AT NO EXTRA CHARGE.
♪
First rule of taking the
world by surprise?
Do something the world
will actually notice.
Introducing the entirely
new Ford Fusion.
With a turbo-charged EcoBoost
engines and a hybrid that
doubles the fuel economy of
the average vehicle.
It's an entirely new idea of
what a car can be.
(Beckett) MARCO,
WE KNOW THAT YOU AND WENDELL
WERE PARTNERS.
YOUR VAN WAS TICKETED
WHEN YOU GUYS PULLED THE JOB.
(Esposito) ROBBERY COULDN'T
PROVE IT BEFORE,
BUT NOW WITH THESE,
WELL, WE GOT YOU.
WELL, IT SEEMS TO ME
LIKE ALL YOU'VE GOT ME FOR
IS STEALING A SAFE.
WHAT'S THE PUNISHMENT FOR THAT,
30 DAYS?
MORE LIKE 30 YEARS
AFTER WE ADD WENDELL
AND WENDY'S MURDERS TO IT.
MURDER?
WHY DON'T YOU TELL US
EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED,
AND WE'LL GET THE D.A.
TO CUT YOU A DEAL?
BUT YOU BETTER HURRY,
BECAUSE THEY'RE
CUTTING THROUGH THAT SAFE,
AND WHEN THEY FIND
THAT DIAMOND BRACELET,
YOU'RE ON YOUR OWN.
(hissing)
(chuckles)
YOU KNOW WHAT I LOVE
ABOUT THIS CASE?
WHAT'S THAT?
FINDING
A PRETTY PINK BRACELET
IN MY BELONGINGS.
YOU KNOW YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE TO RETURN THAT--
I KNOW, RYAN.
I KNOW THAT.
CAN'T YOU JUST LET ME
HAVE THIS MOMENT,
THIS ONE SMALL,
"TREASURE ISLAND,"
INDIANA JONES MOMENT?
SORRY. YOU GOT IT.
WELL, IT'S TOO LATE NOW.
IT'S RUINED.
(hissing continues)
(Marco) ALL I DID
WAS HELP HIM BREAK IN
TO THAT PENTHOUSE.
I SWEAR TO GOD,
I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW THE GUY.
JOHAN OR WENDELL,
WHATEVER, PAID ME 5 GRAND
TO KILL THE ALARMS,
NO QUESTIONS ASKED.
WE DID THE JOB,
HE CAME OUT HAPPY,
SAID "MISSION ACCOMPLISHED,"
WE WENT SEPARATE WAYS.
EXCEPT YOU STILL WANTED
THE BRACELET.
SO YOU WENT AFTER HIM
AND YOU KILLED HIM.
I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW THAT
HE TOOK THAT DAMN BRACELET
UNTIL I READ ABOUT IT
IN THE PAPERS.
AND BY THAT TIME,
HE WAS ALREADY DEAD.
SO I BROKE INTO WENDELL'S,
BUT ALL I FOUND WAS A KEY,
MARKED "STORAGE UNIT."
AND YOU DIDN'T KNOW
WHERE THAT STORAGE UNIT WAS.
SO I KEPT A CLOSE EYE
ON UPCOMING AUCTIONS
UNTIL I FOUND ONE
WITH JOHAN'S NAME.
AS SOON AS I SAW
THE SAFE INSIDE, I KNEW...
THAT'S WHERE HE HAD STASHED
THAT DIAMOND BRACELET.
(hisses)
(clanks)
OH, I LOVE THIS PART--
THE KICK OF ADRENALINE,
THE QUICKENING OF THE HEART,
THOSE LAST FEW DROPS
OF ANTICIPATION.
(squeaks)
IT'S EMPTY.
(squeak)
SO WHERE IS THE BRACELET?
WHEREVER IT IS,
IT'S LAUGHING AT ME.
MAYBE MARCO WAS WRONG,
AND WENDELL SOLD IT
BEFORE HE WAS KILLED.
WELL, THEN WHERE'S
THE MONEY FROM THE SALE?
NO MONEY MEANS
THERE SHOULD BE A BRACELET.
NO BRACELET MEANS
THERE SHOULD BE MONEY.
I THINK THE QUESTION WE SHOULD
BE ASKING IS, HOW DID WENDELL
EVEN PULL OFF A HEIST
LIKE THIS TO BEGIN WITH?
ANGELICA SAID
THAT THE THIEF CRACKED
THE WALL SAFE.
DO YOU KNOW HOW HARD IT IS
TO CRACK A WALL SAFE?
ESPECIALLY SINCE
WENDELL DIDN'T EVEN HAVE
ANY OF THE PROPER EQUIPMENT
IN HIS STORAGE UNIT. IT JUST--
DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE?
THANK YOU.
UNLESS ANGELICA
WASN'T TELLING US THE TRUTH.
LISTEN TO THIS--
ANGELICA WAS SCHEDULED FOR
A BANKRUPTCY HEARING A WEEK AGO,
BUT IT WAS CANCELED BECAUSE
SHE MADE A $2-MILLION PAYMENT
TO HERREDITORS.
THAT'S RIGHT AFTER
THE INSURANCE COMPANY
PAID HER CLAIM
ON THE BRACELET.
WHAT IF THIS WHOLE THING
WAS A PLOY
TO COMMIT INSURANCE FRAUD?
"MISSION ACCOMPLISHED.""
THAT'S WHAT WENDELL SAID
AFTER THE BREAK-IN.
"MISSION ACCOMPLISHED."
RIGHT. HE DIDN'T SAY
HE ACTUALLY STOLE ANYTHING.
THE MISSION WAS TO MAKE IT
LOOK LIKE A ROBBERY.
AND THE BEST WAY
TO MAKE IT LOOK REAL,
TO FOOL THE POLICE
AND THE INSURANCE COMPANY...
IS TO ACTUALLY BREAK IN
YET STEAL NOTHING.
ANGELICA SET
THIS WHOLE THING UP.
AND THE ONLY OTHER PERSON
THAT KNEW WAS WENDELL.
SHE COULDN'T AFFORD
TO LET HIM OR HIS SISTER
EXPOSE HER SECRET.
I CALL THAT MOTIVE
FOR MURDER
AND PROBABLE CAUSE
FOR A SEARCH WARRANT.
OH.
GOOD WORK.
THANK YOU. (slurps)
(man) I'M SORRY, MS. HENLEY.
THEY JUST BARGED IN.
I TRIED TO STOP THEM.
YOU PEOPLE HAVE NO GROUNDS
TO SEARCH MY RESIDENCE.
ACTUALLY... WE DO.
THIS IS OUTRAGEOUS.
SHE'S RIGHT.
YOU KNOW
WHAT YOU SHOULD DO?
OPEN THAT WALL SAFE
AND PROVE US WRONG.
FINE. WE CAN JUST TEAR IT OUT
OF THE WALL IF YOU'D LIKE.
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
NO, NO.
(dial clicking)
(latch clicks)
(squeaks)
WELL, IS IT THERE?
HELLO, GORGEOUS.
♪
How advanced is the
new Ford Fusion?
Well...it has outstanding
performance and handling...
...and it offers a plug-in
hybrid
that gets a projected 100 MPGe.
Of course, there's still
one thing it can't do.
Introducing the entirely
new Ford Fusion.
It's an entirely new idea of
what a car can be.
Of course, some stories are
bigger than others. a story.
Okay guys, here we go.
Everybody say,
'cheeeeeeeee-eeeeeese'.
Got it.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
THIS LITTLE BEAUTY HAS CAUSED
A LOT OF TROUBLE, HASN'T IT?
THAT'S WHAT
BEAUTIFUL THINGS DO, MY DEAR,
AT LEAST TO ME.
SO WHY DIDN'T YOU JUST
SELL IT
AND SOLVE
ALL YOUR MONEY PROBLEMS
INSTEAD OF HIRING WENDELL
TO STAGE A ROBBERY?
I DIDN'T HIRE WENDELL.
I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW HE WAS
INVOLVED IN ALL OF THIS
UNTIL YOU TOLD ME.
SO THE FACT THAT HE BROKE IN
THE SAME NIGHT THAT YOU CALLED
AND REPORTED THIS STOLEN,
THAT'S JUST A COINCIDENCE?
LOOK, WHEN I CAME HOME
AND SAW THAT MY APARTMENT
HAD BEEN BURGLARIZED,
I WAS--I WAS PANICKED,
SHOCKED.
UNTIL I SAW THAT
NOTHING HAD BEEN TAKEN.
SO I THOUGHT THAT IF I
SIMPLY PRETENDED THAT
MY BRACELET HAD BEEN STOLEN,
MM...
IT WOULD SOLVE
ALL MY PROBLEMS.
EXCEPT YOU CREATED
TWO NEW PROBLEMS--
YOUR CHAUFFER
AND HIS SISTER--
BOTH OF WHOM ARE NOW DEAD.
I THINK IT'S TIME FOR ME
TO CALL MY ATTORNEY.
SO SHE ADMITTED
TO INSURANCE FRAUD
HOPING TO AVOID
MURDER CHARGES.
AT LEAST I THINK
THAT'S HER PLAY.
YOU THINK?
YEAH,
SHE'S A DESPERATE WOMAN
ON THE VERGE
OF LOSING HER WEALTH.
THAT'S DEATH
TO SOMEONE LIKE HER.
SHE'S PROBABLY WILLING TO DO
ANYTHING TO AVOID IT--
LIE, STEAL, CHEAT,
AND IN THIS CASE, KILL.
YEAH, BUT THAT STILL DOESN'T
EXPLAIN THE STORAGE LOCKER.
I MEAN, IF WENDELL
DIDN'T STEAL ANYTHING,
WHAT DID HE PUT IN THERE
THAT HIS SISTER
WAS SOSO DESPERA TO GET?
AND IF IT DIDN'T HAVE ANYTHING
TO DO WITH HER MURDER,
WHY WOULD SHE WRITE
THE LOCKER NUMBER IN HER BLOOD?
CASTLE, YOU WENT THROUGH
THAT STORAGE UNIT
WITH A FINE-TOOTH COMB.
YOU SAID THAT THERE'S
NOTHING OF VALUE IN THERE.
WELL, YEAH,
NOTHING OF VALUE TO US.
BUT I MEAN, WHAT ABOUT
SOMETHING OF VALUE TO THEM?
LIKE WHAT?
I DON'T KNOW--A TRINKET,
AN HEIRLOOM.
THE ANSWER'S
IN THERE SOMEWHERE.
IT HAS TO BE.
ANYWAY...
IT'S GETTING LATE.
I HAVE TO DROP OFF ALEXIS
FIRST THING IN THE MORNING.
FRESH START TOMORROW?
SURE.
WALK YOU OUT?
UH, YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'VE GOTTA STICK AUND.
I HAVE TO
GO OVER ANGELICA'S ALIBI.
ALL RIGHT.
(lowered voice) I SO WISH
I COULD KISS YOU RIGHT NOW.
(lowered voice)
YEAH, I KNOW.
THIS IS ME...
SOFTLY TOUCHING YOUR FACE,
PULLING YOU IN
FOR A LONG, SLOW KISS.
AND THIS IS ME
KISSING YOU BACK,
RUNNING MY HANDS
THROUGH YOUR HAIR.
BEST HANDSHAKE EVER.
YEAH. (chuckles)
I THINK MY HAND'S
GETTING A LITTLE SWEATY.
I KNOW.
IT'S KINDA GROSS.
SORRY.
NO WORRIES.
(Martha) OH, ALEXIS.
MY DARLING, FAREWELL.
GOD KNOWS
WHEN WE SHALL MEET AGAIN.
THAT'S SHAKESPEARE, YOU KNOW?
I KNOW.
ALL RIGHT, NO FAREWELLS,
NO GOOD-BYES.
JUST SEE YA LATER, KIDDO.
SEE YOU LATER, GRAM.
I'LL BE IN THE HALL,
DARLING.
ALL RIGHT.
SO...
THIS IS YOUR NEW HOME, HUH?
HEY, LOOK, I GET IT.
I DO.
BUT WHATEVER HAPPENS
BETWEEN BECKETT AND ME,
I WANT YOU TO KNOW--I MEAN,
WE COULD BREAK UP TOMORROW,
WE COULD SPEND THE REST
OF OUR LIVES TOGETHER--
BUT SHE WILL NEVER
TAKE YOUR PLACE IN MY HEART.
WHY WOULD I BE WORRIED
ABOUT DETECTIVE BECKETT
REPLACING ME?
UH, WELL...
YOU WERE ACT--I THOUGHT--
HOW CAN YOU BE SO SMART
AND SO CLUELESS
AT THE SAME TIME?
PRACTICE.
THIS IS
NO MORE ABOUT BECKETT
THAN IT'S ABOUT THE FACT
MY MOTHER ISN'T HERE.
SORRY, HONEY, BUT YOUR MOM...
NO.
SHE'S IN--
NO, IT'S FINE.
IT'S ALWAYS BEEN FINE,
BECAUSE NO MATTER WHAT,
I'D WAKE UP,
AND YOU'D BE THERE,
AND I'D KNOW
THAT EVERYTHING'S FINE.
OH, AND WHEN
YOU WAKE UP HERE...
THEN I'M HERE.
AND YOU'RE THERE.
EVEN THOUGH THERE
IS ONLY 5 MILES AWAY...
(inhales and exhales)
IT'S NOT HERE.
WELL, EVERYTHING IS
GOING TO BE FINE.
AND YOU ARE GONNA BE FINE.
AND THOUGH I AM THERE,
IF YOU NEED ME HERE,
HERE IS WHERE I'LL BE.
HEY, DAD.
I-I KNOW IT'S BEEN
A WHILE, BUT, UM...
COULD YOU DO IT...
ONE LAST TIME?
NO MONSTERS.
YOU SURE?
YEAH, AND IF THERE ARE,
I'LL COME RUNNING.
(sighs)
(sniffles)
DARLING, ARE YOU CRYING?
(voice breaking)
NO, IT'S ALLERGIES.
THE POLLEN COUNT IS HIGH.
THE POLLEN COUNT'S GOTTEN
TO ME, TOO. (crying)
RIGHT?
I KNOW. (continues crying)
OHH.
(people speaking indistinctly)
MM.
YOU CAN GET HOME
BY YOURSELF, RIGHT?
WELL, I--
THANKS. LOVE YOU, MOTHER.
(elevator bell dings)
(man) WHOA.
I KNOW WHERE IT IS.
WHERE WHAT IS?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT IS,
ONLY WHERE IT IS.
WHATEVER WENDELL STOLE
WAS ONLY OF VALUE TO HIM
AND HIS TWIN SISTER.
SO HE WOULD HIDE IT
IN THE ONE PLACE
ONLY SHE WOULD LOOK.
WENDY, WENDELL, TWINS--
AS IN GEMINI COLLECTIBLES.
THIS IS IT.
CASTLE!
IT'S EMPTY.
(footsteps approaching)
OH, THAT CAN'T BE RIGHT.
(gasps) WHAT--
OH, SIR, JUST BREATHE.
WHAT THE HELL
HAVE YOU DONE?
I THOUGHT--
Y-YOU THOUGHT WHAT,
MR. CASTLE?
I JUST THOUGHT THAT WENDELL
WOULD'VE HIDDEN WHAT HE STOLE
INSIDE THE GEMINI--
IT WASN'T WENDELL'S.
IT WAS MINE!
I BROUGHT IT IN
FROM HOME THIS MORNING!
ALL RIGHT,
THAT'S MY BAD.
WAIT. THAT MEANS...
AH. HERE IT IS.
D-D-D--
NO!
(pieces tinkle)
(Beckett) A U.S.B. DRIVE
AND A GLASS EYE.
I DIDN'T SEE THAT COMING.
AND WITH MY BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CREDIT CARD,
I LOVE 'EM EVEN MORE.
I EARN 1% CASH BACK EVERYWHERE,
EVERY TIME.
2% ON GROCERIES.
3% ON GAS.
AUTOMATICALLY.
NO HOOPS TO JUMP THROUGH.
THAT'S 1% BACK ON...
[ toy robot sounds ]
2% ON PUMPKIN PIE.
AND APPLE.
3% BACK ON 4 TRIPS
TO THE AIRPORT.
IT'S AS EASY AS...
-[ man ] 1...
-[ woman ] 2...
[ woman ] 3.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CARD.
APPLY ONLINE OR AT
A BANK OF AMERICA NEAR YOU.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a
Droid Incredible 4G LTE
by HTC for $49.99.
(pieces clatter)
OKAY, SO THE PHOTOS
FROM THIS U.S.B. DRIVE
ARE FROM A CRIME SCENE.
A CRIME SCENE WHERE?
MERCER, PENNSYLVANIA.
THEY'RE ABOUT A DECADE OLD.
IT WAS A HIT-AND-RUN.
(Esposito) WHAT DOES ANY OF THIS
HAVE TO DO WITH A GLASS EYE?
WEREN'T THE TWINS' PARENTS
KILLED IN A CAR CRASH
TEN YEARS AGO?
YEAH, THEY WERE REAR-ENDED,
AND THEIR CAR WENT DOWN
AN EMBANKMENT.
REPORT SAID THAT THEY WERE
TRAPPED INSIDE AND BLED OUT,
AND THAT IF THE PERSON
WHO HIT THEM WOULD'VE STOPPED
AND CALLED FOR HELP,
THEY MIGHT HAVE LIVED.
HEY, GUYS.
LOOK AT THIS PHOTO.
IT'S FROM THE CRIME SCENE,
AND IT'S OF A BROKEN GLASS EYE.
WHAT?
A GLASS EYE?
WAIT A MINUTE.
OF COURSE.
IT ALL MAKES SENSE NOW.
IT DOES?
WENDELL'S OBSESSION--
WHY HE MOVED
FROM PLACE TO PLACE,
WHY HE CAME TO NEW YORK,
WHY HE USED A FAKE NAME
AND A HAD A BOOK
ON PROSTHETIC EYES.
HE WAS--
HE WAS ON A MISSION.
YEAH, BUT ON A MISSION
TO DO WHAT?
WELL, TO FIND
THE PERSON RESPONSIBLE
FOR HIS PARENTS' DEATH.
IN ORDER TO BE SURE,
WENDELL HAD TO STEAL
THE SUSPECT'S GLASS EYE.
THAT'S WHAT THE HEIST
WAS ABOUT.
AND LIKE FINGERPRINTS, HE USED
THAT PHOTO TO COMPARE THE EYES.
A LA RICHARD KIMBLE,
BUT INSTEAD OF LOOKING FOR
A ONE-ARMED MAN...
HE WAS LOOKING
FOR A ONE-EYED MAN.
OR IN OUR CASE,
A ONE-EYED WOMAN.
I'M NOT SAYING A WORD
WITHOUT MY LAWYER.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO,
BUT YOU MIGHT WANT TO LISTEN.
WE KNOW WHAT WENDELL STOLE.
THAT'S IT.
I'M CALLING MY ATTORNEY.
UH, MAY I?
YES.
THANK YOU.
MM-HMM.
I'VE WORKED
A LOT OF MURDER CASES,
WAITING PATIENTLY
FOR THE DAY
I COULD UNEQUIVOCALLY EXCLAIM,
THE BUTLER DID IT.
WHAT?
MUST HAVE BEEN A SHOCK--
ALL THESE YEARS LATER,
AFTER YOU PUT ALL THAT
BEHIND YOU,
TO HAVE SOMEONE
WALK INTO YOUR LIFE
AND STIR IT ALL
BACK UP AGAIN.
(Angelica) KIRBY.
WHAT'S HE TALKING ABOUT?
YOUR LIVE-IN BUTLER
CAUSED A CAR ACCIDENT
AND THEN FLED THE SCENE.
BECAUSE HE DID,
TWO PEOPLE LOST THEIR LIVES.
AND THOSE PEOPLE
WERE WENDELL'S PARENTS.
(Kirby) THAT IS...
ABSOLUTELY RIDICULOUS.
YOU CAN'T PROVE ANY OF IT.
YOUR D.N.A. WAS ON
THE PROSTHETIC EYE
THAT WENDELL STOLE.
AND IT'S A MATCH TO THE D.N.A.
FOUND ON THE SHELL CASING
IN WENDY'S HOTEL ROOM.
(Castle) IT'S ALL OVER.
I WORKED...
SO HARD TO PUT THAT NIGHT--
THAT HORRIBLE NIGHT--
BEHIND ME.
AND THEN THE BREAK-IN.
OF ALL THE THINGS
TO STEAL,
MY SPARE EYE
FROM OFF MY BUREAU.
THAT'S WHEN I PUT IT
ALL TOGETHER--
WHO THE NEW CHAUFFER
TRULY WAS
AND WHAT HE WAS TRYING
TO PROVE.
BUT YOU--
YOU HAVE TO UNDERSTAND...
I COULDN'T BRING
THEIR PARENTS BACK.
I-I COULDN'T.
WHY SHOULD I SUFFER?
KIRBY SMITH,
YOU'RE UNDER ARREST
FOR THE MURDERS OF WENDELL
AND WENDY DUPREE.
(handcuffs click)
AND I AM SURE THAT
THE STATE OF PENNSYLVANIA
WILL BE ADDING TWO COUNTS
OF VEHICULAR MANSLAUGHTER
TO THAT.
(Beckett)
KIRBY MADE A FULL CONFESSION.
HE READ AN ARTICLE
ABOUT A RECENT MUGGING
IN THE SUBWAY STATION,
AND DECIDED
TO KILL WENDELL THERE
BECAUSE HE KNEW THAT
THE CAMERAS WOULDN'T BE WORKING.
(Castle) BUT THE EVIDENCE
THAT WENDELL STOLE
WAS STILL OUT THERE,
SO WAS HIS SISTER WENDY.
WHEN SHE STARTED
POKING AROUND STORAGE SPACES,
KIRBY TRACKED HER
TO THE HOTEL AND SHOT HER.
WORTHLESS BASTARD.
I'M SORRY.
HE TOOK OUT
THEIR WHOLE FAMILY.
GOOD JOB, DETECTIVE.
THANK YOU.
AND... SHE HATES ME AGAIN.
YEAH, WELL, THOSE GEMINI DOLLS
OBVIOUSLY MEANT A LOT TO HER.
YEAH, I WONDER WHAT
THAT STORY IS.
I WONDER
WHAT THOSE STORIES ARE.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO WITH
ALL OF THAT STUFF, CASTLE?
WELL, I'LL GIVE THE CLIMBING
EQUIPMENT TO JAVIER,
AND THEN, UH,
DONATE THE REST, I GUESS.
IT SERVED ITS PURPOSE.
BROUGHT JUSTICE TO HIS FAMILY.
BUT IT JUST GOES TO SHOW YOU
THAT EVERYONE AND EVERYTHING
HAS A STORY,
INCLUDING YOUR LITTLE
STICK MAN THERE.
SO...
YOU WANT TO TAKE
ANOTHER SHOT?
ACTUALLY, NO.
I THOUGHT ABOUT
WHAT YOU SAID.
AND YOU'RE RIGHT.
JUST BECAUSE WE'VE BEEN...
SHAKING HANDS
A LOT...
DOESN'T MEAN THAT
I HAVE THE RIGHT TO PRY.
SO...
WHEN YOU ARE READY,
YOU'LL TELL ME.
CONEY ISLAND.
WE, UH, WE HAD A RECEPTION
AT OUR PLACE
AFTER MY MOM'S FUNERAL,
AND... IT WAS MISERABLE.
I WAS MISERABLE,
AND MY DAD...
TOOK MY HAND
AND HE SAID, UH,
"LET'S GET THE HELL
OUTTA HERE, KATIE."
AND WE TOOK THE "Q" TRAIN,
AND WE WENT
UP TO CONEY ISLAND.
AND WE WALKED
UP AND DOWN THAT BEACH,
JUST ENJOYING OURSELVES.
WE WERE STILL
IN OUR FUNERAL CLOTHES.
AND THE BEST PART WAS THAT
WE MADE THIS LITTLE GUY
OUT OF THE TWIGS AND TWINE
THAT WASHED UP ON THE SHORE.
DOES THAT MAKE THAT DAY
A BAD MEMORY
OR A GOOD ONE?
BOTH.
HE'S A REMINDER...
THAT EVEN ON THE WORST DAYS,
THERE'S A POSSIBILITY
FOR JOY.
NICE.
SO WE'LL TALK TONIGHT?
I CAN'T WAIT.
MY LITTLE GIRL.
ALEXIS' MOVING OUT
GOT ME TO THINKING.
AND AFTER MANY HOURS
OF SOUL SEARCHING,
I HAVE MADE A DECISION.
HAVE YOU NOW?
YES.
I HAVE DECIDED, OUT OF
THE GOODNESS OF MY HEART,
THAT I WILL CONTINUE
TO LIVE HERE--
RENT-FREE.
PLEASE DON'T INTERRUPT.
I WILL CONTINUE TO LIVE HERE
SO THAT YOU, RICHARD...
WILL NEVER, EVER BE ALONE.
YOU'D DO THAT FOR ME,
MOTHER?
(voice breaks)
IT'S A PARENT'S SACRIFICE.
MM.
-- Captions by VITAC --
>> LIVE FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT TONIGHT.  LAURA IS
THERE AS YOUNG VICTIMS ARE LAID
TO REST WHILE STRANGERS COME
FROM FAR AND WIDE TO PAY THEIR
RESPECTS.
>> WHAT WAS BAY AREA COUPLE
DOING TONIGHT THAT BROUGHT OUT
THE HAZMAT TEAM?
STAY WITH US 7 NEWS BEGINS