ADULTS.
AMONG THE ADULTS THE SHOOTER'S
MOTHER NANCY LANZA ALSO TEACHER
VICKI SOTO.
THE MOTHER NANCY MAY HAVE BEEN A
VOLUNTEER OR SUBSTITUTE TEACHER
AT THE SCHOOL.
ONE OF THE OTHER ADULTS KILLED
WAS 47-YEAR-OLD DAWN HOCHSPRUNG
THE SCHOOL'S PRINCIPAL.
WE P WANT TO GO LIVE WITH THE
LATEST IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> GOOD MORNING.
ANY MINUTE WE EXPECT POLICE WILL
RELEASE THE NAMES OF THE VICTIMS
AS THE COMMUNITY BEGINS TO
PROCESS THE UNIMAGINABLE HORROR
OF STUDENTS LOST AT SCHOOL.
>> IT ALL STARTED ON A SEEMINGLY
ORDINARY DAY IN THE MOST
UNLIKELIEST PLACES A SLEEPY NEW
ENGLAND TOWN ONE OF THE WORST
MASS SHOOTINGS IN THIS NATION'S
HISTORY.
>> SANDY HOOK SCHOOL.
CALLER IS INDICATING SHE THINKS
SOMEONE IS SHOOTING IN THE
BUILDING.
>> AUTHORITIES SAY 20-YEAR-OLD
ADAM LANZA SEEN AS A TEENAGER
HERE CAME TO THE SCHOOL WEARING
A BULLETPROOFED VEST AND ARMED
WITH A SEMI AUTOMATIC ASSAULT
RIFLE AND TWO HIGH POWERED
PISTOLS LIKE THESE.
THEY HAVE RECOVERED MORE THAN 3
WEAPONS.
>> EVERYONE WAS SCARED.
A REALLY BIG KID INSIDE OF MY
CLASS, I HAVE NEVER SEEN HIM CRY
AND HE WAS CRYING.
IT WAS REALLY SCARY FOR ALL OF
US.
>> HOURS BEFORE POLICE SAY LANZA
HAD SHOT HIS MOTHER IN HER HOME
AND HEADED TO THE SCHOOL WHERE
HE KILLED 26 PEOPLE MOSTLY
CHILDREN AND THEN HIMSELF.
AFTER THE RAMPAGE ENDED THEY LED
STUDENTS TO A SCHOOLHOUSE TO A
NEARBY FIRE STATION.
>> WE GOT IN A LINE AND WE HAD
TO CLOSE OUR EYES AND WE ALL PUT
OUR HANDS ON OTHER PEOPLE'S
SHOULDERS AND THEN OUR TEACHER
HOLD THE FIRST PERSON'S HAND AND
SHE LED US OUT.
>> FRANTIC PARENTS ARRIVED AT
THE SCHOOL SIMPLY HOPING TO FIND
THEIR CHILDREN ALIVE.
>> HEARTBREAKING.
IT IS HEARTBREAKING.
>> AUTHORITIES ARE STILL
SEARCHING FOR ANSWERS.
>> WE WILL GO BACKWARDS AS FAR
AS WE HAVE TO GO IN THIS
INVESTIGATION.
HOPEFULLY WE WILL STUMBLE ON
ANSWERS.
>> THEY ARE QUESTIONING HIS
BROTHER RYAN AND FATHER PETER TO
FIND OUT WHAT HAPPENED.
THE HORROR STILL DOESN'T SEEM
REAL RESIDENTS SAY.
>> SHOULD I BE PINCHED TO SEE IF
IT REALLY IS REAL.
IT'S HEART WRENCHING.
>> FEELS LIKE A DREAM AND A BAD
DREAM.
>> IT'S A NIGHTMARE.
>> SOME OF THE BODIES HAVE BEEN
MOVED FROM THE SCHOOL.
WE EXPECT THE REST WILL BE
REMOVED LATER TODAY.
CONNECTICUT DOES NOT HAVE MUF
NED CAL EXAM -- ENOUGH MEDICAL
EXAMINERS AND WILL ASK FOR HELP.
>>> THANK YOU.
AS TIMON REPORTED THE SHOOTER
HAS BEEN IDENTIFIED AS ADAM
LANZA.
THIS IS A PICTURE OF HIM FROM
2005 ABC NEWS REPORTS HE GAINED
ACCESS TO THE SCHOOL BY BREAKING
A GLASS WINDOW NEAR THE FRONT
DOOR.
A FEW HOURS FROM NOW A PRAYER
VIGIL IS EXPECT TO DO TAKE PLACE
IN SAN FRANCISCO AS THE AIDS
MEMORIAL GROVE.
VIGILS POPPED UP ALL OVER THE
COUNTRY INCLUDING THIS ONE AT
MILL VALLEY WHERE 20 PEOPLE
TURNED OUT TO REMEMBER THE
VICTIMS IN CONNECTICUT.
WE HAVE MORE ON ANOTHER VIGIL
HELD IN WALNUT CREEK LAST NIGHT.
>>> THIS CANDLELIGHT VIGIL CAME
TOGETHER WITHIN JUST A FEW
HOURS.
ORGANIZER ASHLEY MONTH REFELT
COMPELLED TO DO SOMETHING AFTER
WATCHING NEWS REPORTS THROUGH
OUT THE DAY.
>> OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN BUT
WHEN WE GATHER HERE LIKE THIS IT
SHOWS OUR SPIRITS AREN'T BROKEN.
>> AMONG THOSE IN THE CROWD WERE
ELEMENTARY AGED STUDENTS.
>> DID YOU HEAR IT THROUGH A
FRIEND OR ON THE PHONE?
>> I HEARD IT FROM MY MOM.
>> HIS MOTHER TELLS ME HE HAD A
CONVERSATION WITH THEM ABOUT THE
SHOOTING IN CONNECTICUT WHEN SHE
PICKED HIM UP FROM SCHOOL.
>> I THOUGHT IT WAS IMPORTANT
FOR THEM TO KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
USUALLY I TRY TO SHIELD THEM
FROM EVENTS BUT THIS WAS TOO
CLOSE.
>> SHE HELPED THEM UNDERSTAND
WHAT FAMILIES ARE GOING THROUGH.
>> I CAN'T IMAGE GOING TO THE
SCHOOL HOPING THAT IT WASN'T MY
CHILD IN CLASSROOM, BUT AT THE
SAME TIME IT WASN'T THEN YOU ARE
HORRIFIED BY THE FACT THAT THAT
WAS MY DAUGHTER'S BEST FRIEND IN
THAT CLASSROOM.
>> BILL MILLER IS HEAD OF THE
CLASSROOM IN WALNUT CREEK.
>> I TALKED TO THEM AND SAID
THESE ARE OUR CHILDREN.
THESE WERE OUR STUR DENTS.
THESE WERE MY TEACHERS THESE
WERE OUR TEACHERS.
THESE WERE OUR COLLEAGUES THAT
FELL.
>> A COUPLE DOZEN PEOPLE TURNED
OUT FOR THE VIGIL IN WALNUT
CREEK.
THEY LEFT BEHIND A CANDLE AND A
CARD AND FLOWERS TO HONOR THOSE
WHO WERE KILLED IN CONNECTICUT
ON FRIDAY.
>> HERE IS A VIGIL OF ONE IN SAN
JOSE.
THE MOTHER OF A 6-YEAR-OLD
SHARED THIS PHOTO WITH US ON
TWITTER.
THE YOUNG BOY IS LIGHTING A
HANDLE FOR THE CHILDREN AT
NEWTOWN SOME HIS AGE.
THE SIGN READS SAN JOSE LOVES
SHES, CONNECTICUT.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>>> IT HAS BEEN EMOTIONAL FOR
PARENTS.
YOU MAY BE WONDERING HOW TO TALK
TO YOUR CHILDREN ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED.
THE SEASON OF PSYCHOLOGY AT
SANTA CLARA UNIVERSITY SAYS YOU
NEED TO DEAL WITH YOUR OWN
FEELINGS FEAR, ANGER ANXIETY AND
THEN SPEAK TO YOUR CHILD CALMLY
AND LISTEN INTENTLY.
THE TIME TO DO IT IS NOW BEFORE
YOUR CHILD SEES THIS SOMEWHERE
ELSE.
>> I WOULD TALK TODAY.
I DON'T THINK IT'S WORTH WAITING
UNTIL THE END OF THE WEEKEND OR
WAITING UNTIL THERE'S A RIGHT
MOMENT.
THE MOMENT IS NOW.
THE KIDS ARE EXPERIENCING THIS.
THEY HAVE TO UNDERSTAND WHAT
DOES THIS MEAN WHEN AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HAS THIS KIND
OF TRAGEDY.
>> THE DOCTOR SAYS YOU SHOULD
REASSURE YOUR KIDS THEY ARE SAFE
IN SCHOOL BEFORE THEY GO BACK TO
CLASS ON MONDAY.
WE HAVE MORE COMING UP IN THIS
NEWSCAST.
STAY WITH ABC 7 NEWS FOR
CONTINUING COVERAGE.
YOU CAN RECEIVE URGENT UPDATES
ON YOUR SMART PHONE BY
DOWNLOADING OUR FREE ABC 7 NEWS
APP AND OPTING FOR THE PUSH
NOTIFICATIO
NOTIFICATIONS.
SIGN UP AT ABCNEWS.COM.
WE ARE ALSO UPDATING OUR
FACEBOOK PAGE AT
FACEBOOK.COM/ABC 7 NEWS AND ON
TWITTER AT ABC 7 NEWS BAY AREA.
TIME NOW TO CHECK IN WITH LISA
ARGIN FOR A CHECK OF THE
FORECAST.
>> WE HAVE A WEAK WEATHER SYSTEM
THAT SHOULD BRING US RAIN LATER
ON TODAY.
HERE'S A LOOK AT HOW FAR NORTH
IT IS.
YOU CAN SEE LLEYTON AND UKIA.
IT WILL TAKE SOME TIME TO GET
HERE.
BEFORE THEN WE HAVE DRY BUT COLD
CONDITIONS.
IT IS 32 IN LIVERMORE.
GOOD MORNING ANTIOCH.
36 SAN FRANCISCO AND 32 AND FOG
IN THE NORTH BAY AROUND SANTA
ROSA.
HEADING OUT THE DOOR DRY AND
COLD UPPER 20s TO THE MID 40s.
BY THIS AFTERNOON LIGHT RAIN
DEVELOPS WITH LOWER 50s.
WE WILL KEEP THE SHOWERS IN THE
FORECAST THROUGH OUT THE EVENING
HOURS.
I WILL TELL YOU HOW MUCH RAIN TO
EXPECT FOR THE REST OF THE
WEEKEND AND THE WEEK AHEAD.
KEEP THE UMBRELLAS HANDY.
>> WILL DO.
THANK YOU LISA.
OUR COVERAGE OF THE DEADLY
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SHOOTLING
CONTINUES.
UP NEXT YOU WILL HEAR TWO YOUNG
BROTHERS DESCRIBE THE DAY THAT
WILL FOREVER CHANGE THEIR LIVES.
MORE ON THE SCHOOL TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT.
STAY WITH US.
6ñZP
ERG WAS FINE.
EVERYTHING WAS JUST NORMAL AS A
REGULAR FRIDAY MORNING WOULD BE
TO EVERYONE.
AND THEN IT ALL JUST CHANGED.
>> THEN IT ALL JUST CHANGED.
>> IT ALL CHANGED.
>> THAT'S HOW BROTHERS ETHAN AND
BEN 4TH GRADE STUDENTS AT SANDY
HOOKS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
DESCRIBED THE CHAOS WHEN THE
FIRST SHOTS WERE FIRED.
WE HAVE LIVE COVERAGE ON ABC 7
NEWS THIS MORNING.
THERE WILL BE A SPECIAL EDITION
OF "GOOD MORNING AMERICA" AT
7:00 A.M.  IT WILL BE BROADCAST
FROM THE SCENE OF THE SHOOTING
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> AN INVESTIGATION IS UNDERWAY
AFTER AN OFF DUTY CHP OFFICER
WAS KILLED IN A HEAD ON ACCIDENT
IN FAIRFIELD.
IT HAPPENED BEFORE 6:00 ON
HIGHWAY 12 NEAR RED TOP ROAD
LAST NIGHT.
AUTHORITIES TELL US THE OFFICER
WAS ON HIS PERSONAL MOTORCYCLE
WHEN HE HIT A PICKUP TRUCK
TURNING LEFT IN FRONT OF HIM.
THE OFFICER WAS THROWN AND HIT
BY THE HONDA YOU SEE THERE.
THE UNIDENTIFIED OFFICER WAS
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCENE.
>>> AN 82-YEAR-OLD MAN IS FACING
FELONY CHARGES OF VEHICULAR
MANSLAUGHTER AFTER HE WAS
INVOLVED IN A TEAR FY RRIFYING
THAT TOOK THREE LIVES TODAY IN
SAN MATEO COUNTY.
>> SKY 7 H. D. WAS OVER THE
SCENE AFTER THE CRASH ON I 280.
THE TAN LEX SIS PULLED NEXT TO
THE MEDIAN.
IT WAS THEN THIS VOLKSWAGON
SWERVED AND CRASHED INTO THE
LEXUS.
>> FOUR PEOPLE TOTAL.
3 OF THE PEOPLE WERE PRONOUNCED
AT THE SCENE.
>> KILLED AT THE SCENE A WOMAN
IN HER 40s A 28-YEAR-OLD MAN AND
28-YEAR-OLD WOMAN.
IT WASN'T IMMEDIATELY CLEAR WHO
WAS INAND OUTSIDE OF THE CAR.
THE EXTENT OF THE DAMAGE AND
FORCE OF IMPACT ARE IMPORTANT
CLUES FOR INVESTIGATORS.
>> FESPEED WAS A FACTOR.
>> DRIVER OF THIS BLACK
VOLKSWAGON IS AN 82-YEAR-OLD MAN
FROM THE BAY AREA.
HE WAS TAKEN TO SANFORD MEDICAL
CENTER FOR NONLIFE THREATENING
INJURIES.
ONCE RELEASED HE WILL FACE
FELONY CHARGES OF VEHICULAR
MANSLAUGHTER.
IT CAUSED A TRAFFIC BACKUP FOR
MILES.
>> INVESTIGATORS SAY NEATER
ALCOHOL OR DRUGS WERE FOUND NEAR
THE CRASH.
>> METEOROLOGIST LISA ARGIN HERE
NEXT WITH A LOOK AT WHAT WE CAN
EXPECT THIS WEEKEND.
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
>> VERY SEASONAL.
WE ARE LESS THAN A WEEK AWAY
FROM THE OFFICIAL STARTS OF
WINTER.
COLD TEMPERATURES BELOW FREEZING
IN PARTS OF OUR VALLEYS.
RIGHT NOW HERE IS A LOOK AT
EMERIVILLE WHERE WE HAVE 40s A
LITTLE MILDER CLOSE TORE THE
BAY.
I WILL TALK ABOUT RAIN TODAY.
A LITTLE BIT AND LESS TOMORROW.
YES YOU DID.
NO I DIDN'T,
NO I DIDN'T.
YES YOU DID,
YES YOU DID.
NO I DIDN'T,
NO I DIDN'T.
YES YOU DID.
DID NOT.
[ Male Announcer ]
FIND SOME PEACE THIS HOLIDAY.
GET AN 8 PIECE MEAL
NOW WITH A DOZEN
DELICIOUS COOK-STORE.
THE KFC FESTIVE FEAST.
ALL FOR JUST $19.99.
TODAY TASTES SO GOOD.
>> IN RESPONSE TO OVERWHELMING
CRITICISM THE UNIVERSITY OF
CALIFORNIA DECIDED TO NICKS
PLANS TO USE A COLORFUL LOGO.
IT FEATURE AS SMALL SCENE
NESTLED IN A SHIELD INSIDE A U.
IT CAME UNDER FIRE FOR STUDENTS
AND ALUMNI WHO CALLED IT BLAND
AND NONDESCRIPT.
THEY ASKED THE UNIVERSITY TO GO
BACK TO THE CLASSIC LOGO IT USED
FOR 144 YEARS.
THE SPACE AGENCY WILL
INTENTIONALLY CRASH THE TWO
PROBES INTO A CLIFF NEAR THE
LUNAR NORTH POLE.
THEY LAUNCHED THE GRAIL MISSION
IN SEPTEMBER OF LAST YEAR.
IT HAS BEEN A HUGE SUCCESS.
IT WILL END WITH A BANK IT
SOUNDS LIKE.
>> HERE ON EARTH.
>> IT IS QUIET AND COLD THIS
MORNING.
NO RAIN YET.
WE ARE EXPECTING RAIN NOT ONLY
TODAY BUT TOMORROW AS WELL.
HERE IS A LIVE LOOK FROM OUR
ROOF CAMERA.
MORE CLOUDS IN THE NORTH BAY.
THE LOWER CLOUDS BRINGING FOG
AROUND THE BAY.
WE HAVE CLEAR SKIES CENTRAL
COAST.
7 DEGREES IN TRUCKY.
SHOW AGO LITTLE LIGHT RAIN WELL
UP TO THE NORTH NEAR
LLEYTONVILLE.
IT IS 89, 90 MILES AWAY.
YOU CAN SEE MORE OF IT.
GOOD MORNING LIVERMORE 32 FOR
YOU WITH FOG DEVELOPING.
46 IN SAN FRANCISCO.
40 MOUNTAIN VIEW, 38 IN SAN
JOSE.
QUARTER MILE VISIBILITY IN
LIVERMORE.
MILE AND A QUARTER IN SANTA
ROSA.
ELSEWHERE WITH THE CLEAR
CONDITIONS IT IS CHILLY ALL OF
THE WAY DOWN TO SAN JOSE.
WE HAVE THE COLD TEMPERATURES
AND THE RAIN DEVELOPING BY THE
AFTERNOON.
MAYBE BEFORE THAT IN THE NORTH
BAY.
CHANCE OF SHOWERS LINGERS
THROUGH TOMORROW.
ANOTHER SYSTEM BEHIND IT THAT
WILL GIVE A LITTLE MORE PRECIP
BY LATE SUNDAY INTO YOUR MORNING
COMMUTE.
NOTHING TOO SIGNIFICANT UNTIL
PERHAPS THE END OF NEXT WEEK.
HERE IS A LOOK AT WHAT'S TO
COME.
YOU CAN SEE THE CLOUDS TO THE
NORTH AND WEST OF US.
HERE IS THE WEAK SYSTEM.
SPREADS OVER THE BAY LITTLE
SUNSHINE ACROSS THE CENTRAL
COAST AND SOUTH BAY THIS
MORNING.
CLOUDS AND RAIN THROUGH OUT THE
LATER AFTERNOON IN SAN JOSE.
WELL UP TO THE NORTH WE HAVE
COLD AIR ALREADY AT THE -- IN
THE VALLEYS.
SNOW LEVEL LOOKING FOR SNOW
AROUND LAKE COUNTY.
THERE IS THE LIGHT RAIN.
YOU MAY MISS IT YOU MAY NOT SEE
MUCH AT ALL.
BUT THROUGH 11:00 A CHANCE OF
SHOWERS IN THE NORTH BAY.
BY SUNDAY WE ARE FAVORING THE
NORTH BAY SUNDAY MORNING.
NOT A WHOLE LOT GOING ON SUNDAY
AFTERNOON.
OVERNIGHT HOURS INTO SUNDAY
MORNING THAT'S THE NEXT SYSTEM
WITH MORE MILD CONDITIONS A
LITTLE MORE RAIN AS WELL.
TRACE AMOUNTS IN THE SOUTH BAY A
TENTH IN THE EAST BAY.
FOUR TENTHS PERHAPS IN THE EAST
BAY.
LOOK AT THAT ONLY 45 DEGREES UP
THERE.
51 FREMONT.
LOW 50s, 51 HOLLISTER.
HERE'S A LOOK AHEAD YOU NOTICE
WE ARE STAYING COOL WITH A
CHANCE OF RAIN EVERY DAY EXCEPT
TUESDAY IS LOOKING MORE SPOTTY
AND WEDNESDAY LOOKING AT MORE
SUNSHINE.
NOT WARMING UP TOO MUCH.
SEASONAL AND WE HAVE WINTER
ARRIVING IN LESS THAN A WEEK.
THERE GOES.
>> FEELS LIKE IT'S HERE RIGHT
NOW.
>> THANK YOU, LISA.
>>> THE NBA OBSERVED MOMENTS OF
SIGH ENLENS BEFORE EACH OF THE
GAMES LAST NIGHT TO HONOR THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING VICTIMS IN
CONNECTICUT.
THIS WAS THE SCENE ON ESPN LAST
NIGHT IN DENVER WHERE FANS WERE
ASKED TO STAND BEFORE THE START
OF THE NUGGETS GRIZZLY GAME.
LARRY VEAL BEGINS OUR SPORTS
WITH THE WARRIORS AND MAGIC.
>> GOOD MORNING EVERYBODY.
SPORTS CLEARLY A DIVERSION AFTER
WHAT WE SAW YESTERDAY IN
CONNECTICUT.
WITH THAT IN MIND WE WILL START
WITH THE WARRIORS TRYING TO KEEP
THEIR ROAD TRIP GOING IN
ORLANDO.
FIVE WINS THAT'S THE MOST THE
WARRIORS HAVE HAD ON EAST COAST
TRIP SINCE 1962.
THEY DID NOT HAVE IT IN THIS
GAME.
WELCOME TO THE BLOCK PARTY.
ORLANDO BLOCKED 10 SHOTS IN THE
FIRST HALF.
MAGIC 7-13 AGAINST THE REST OF
THE LEAGUE 2-0 AGAINST GOLDEN
STATE.
JJ REDIC BEATS THE BUZZER.
HE HAD 16.
DAVID LEE BRINGING IT.
24 POINTS 15 REBOUNDS, HIS 6TH
DOUBLE DOUBLE IN A ROW.
NELSON MAKING IT LOOK EASY.
SUCCESSFUL ROAD TRIP.
THEY WILL END THE TRIP TONIGHT
IN ATLANTA.
LAKERS TRYING TO SNAP THEIR FOUR
GAME SKID AGAINST THE LAST
PLACE.
KOBE BRYANT BEHIND THE BACK TO
DWIGHT HOWARD.
12 POINTS FOR HOWARD.
WITH THE WIZARDS ONCE EVERY 10
YEARS YOU GET A GOOD TEAM.
ALLEY-OOP TO WEBSTER.
HERE COMING DOWN THE LANE.
SOMEBODY GOT A BLOCK OUT.
NOBODY EVER BOXES OUT ANY MORE.
LAKERS STOPPED THE SKID 102-96.
STILL THEY ARE 10-14.
THE DE LA SALLE HIGH SCHOOL
FOOTBALL TEAM LOOKS TO FWIN THER
FOURTH STATE TITLE AGAINST
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA.
THEY ARE TWO WINS SHY OF 400 IN
HIS FANTASTIC CAREER.
HE IS OPENLY TALKING ABOUT
RETIREMENT.
COACH LAD HAS LED DE LA SALLE
FOR 34 YEARS.
IT IS THE ONE AND ONLY JOB HE
EVER WANTED.
>> I WANTED TO BE A HIGH SCHOOL
TEACHER.
I WANTED TO BE AT THIS SCHOOL.
THAT'S WHEN I WAS 24 YEARS OLD.
IT NEVER CHANGED.
NEVER GOT WANDER LUST OR WANTED
TO JUMP UP A LEVEL.
OR ANYTHING LIKE THAT.
IT HAS BEEN VERY REWARDING.
IT HAS BEEN A GOOD CAREER.
I HAVE NO REGRETS WHATSOEVER.
>>> HE IS AN AMAZING COACH.
THE 49ERS HEAD TO NEW ENGLAND
FOR THE SHOW DOWN AGAINST THE
PATRIOTS.
IF THE NINERS WIN THEY CLINCH
THE PLAY OFF SPOT.
EVERYBODY HAS BEEN TALKING ABOUT
THE QUARTERBACK.
BUT THE BEST DEFENSIVE WEAPON
MR. FRANK GORE.
HE REACHED THE 1,000 YARD MARK
FOR THE 6TH TIME IN HIS CAREER.
THE FRANCHISE RECORD RUSHING
TOUCHDOWNS AT 50.
BANGED UP FOR THIS SEASON BUT HE
FINDS A WAY TO BLOCK OUT THE
PAIN.
>> IN CRAIG'S CASE AND A LOT OF
THE CASES THE LOVE OF THE GAME,
HOW MUCH HE LOVES FOOTBALL, HOW
MUCH HE LIKES PRACTICING AND
PLAYING THIS GAME THAT PLAYS A
BIG PART IN MAKING HIM SUCH A
DURABLE GUY WEEK AFTER WEEK.
>> AND RAIDERS HOST THE CHIEFS
ON SUNDAY.
BAY AREA FAVORITE PUTS HIS WBO
JUNIOR FEATHER WEIGHT TITLE ON
THE LINE AGAINST THE FLEXING
JORGE ARSAY.
DONAR WEIGHED IN AT 121 NANNED.
ARSAY HAD TO TAKE EVERYTHING OFF
TO BARELY MAKE WEIGHT AT 122
POUNDS EVEN.
THAT IS A WRAP ON MORNING
SPORTS.
MIKE SHOEMAN WILL BE HERE AT 5,
6 AND 11:00 P.M.
HAVE A GREAT WEEKEND EVERYBODY.
I AM LARRY BEAL.
>> OUR COVERAGE CONTINUES.
A COMMUNITY IS IN MOURNING
TODAY.
WE ARE WAITING FOR A NEWS
CONFERENCE ABOUT YESTERDAY'S
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SHOOTING.
PLUS --
>> TO BE ABSOLUTELY QUIET.
I SAID THERE ARE BAD GUYS OUT
THERE NOW WE NEED TO WAIT FOR
THE GOOD GUYS.
>> IN ALL OF THE TRAGEDY SOME
LIFE SAVING STORIES THE TEACHERS
WHO KEPT CHILDREN SAFE AND CALM
AS THE GUNMAN OPENED FIRE IN
CLASSROOMS.
>> PLUS PEOPLE ACROSS THE BAY
AREA ARE GATHERING TO MOURN AND
REMEMBER THE CONNECTICUT
VICTIMS.
I AM KIERRA CLAPPER LIVE IN
GOLDEN GATE PARK.
I WILL TELL YOU ABO
>> IT IS 6:28.
THESE ARE LIVE PICTURES FROM
NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT.
WE ARE WAITING FOR A NEWS
CONFERENCE WHERE AUTHORITIES
WILL GIVE AN UPDATE ON THE
INVESTIGATION.
THE INVESTIGATION INTO THE
DEADLY SHOOTING AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL THERE ARE 27
VICTIMS.
20 OF THOSE ARE CHILDREN LEAVING
7 ADULTS.
WE ALSO LEARNED THIS MORNING THE
SHOOTER ADAM LANZA BROUGHT THREE
GUNS INTO THE SCHOOL.
THE WEAPONS WERE REGISTERED TO
HIS MOTHER.
THIS MORNING THE COMMUNITY IN
MOURNING AND ASKING WHY DID THIS
HAPPEN?
>> ALL UNITS THE INDIVIDUAL I
HAVE ON THE PHONE IS CONTINUING
TO HEAR WHAT HE BELIEVES TO BE
GUN SHOTS.
>> THE FIRST WORDS ARE CHILLING
IT ONLY GOT WORSE.
>> THEY ARE REPORTING MULTIPLE
FATALITIES INVOLVED IN THE
SHOOTING AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
>> WITH EACH NEW REPORT THE
HORRORS DEEP PEN.
>> THE NUMBER DEAD CLOSER TO 30
THAN TO 20.
SAD EMPLOYS OF THEM ARE
CHILDREN.
>> THIS MORNING WE KNOW THE
DEATH TOLL IS 27.
20 OF THOSE KILLED ARE CHILDREN
BETWEEN THE AGES OF 5 AND 10.
THERE ARE STILL MANY QUESTIONS
ABOUT FRIDAY'S SHOOTING AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE MOST COMMON ONE IS WHY?
>> IN THESE TIMES OF TROUBLE AND
THEN THE UNTHINKABLE HAPPENS IN
OUR VERY MIDST.
OUR FAITH IS TESTED.
>> AS RESIDENTS OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT CAME TOGETHER IN
VIGILS FRIDAY NIGHT LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS CONTINUE
TO WORK AT THE SCENE TO PIECE
TOGETHER WHAT HAPPENED.
>> WE CONSIDER AN INVESTIGATION
LIKE THIS TO BE MASSIVE.
IT'S LIKE A BIG PUZZLE.
WE HAVE TO PUT PIECES TOGETHER
TO DRAW A PICTURE AS TO HOW AND
WHY THIS OCCURRED.
>> AT THE CENTER OF THE PUZZLE
ADAM LANZA THE 20-YEAR-OLD
IDENTIFIED AS THE SHOOTER.
HE HAD NO KNOWN CRIMINAL RECORD
BEFORE ENTERING THE SCHOOL
FRIDAY MORNING DRESSED IN BLACK
FATIGUES AND A MILITARY VEST.
HE WAS FOUND DEAD IN THE
CLASSROOM APPARENTLY BY HIS OWN
HAND.
A FORMER CLASSMATE WHO KNEW
LANZA DURING GRAMMAR SCHOOL
DESCRIBED HIM AS QUIET.
>> HE WAS QUIET.
HE STUK TO H-- STUCK TO HIMSELF.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU COULD SAY
YOU COULD PREDICT THIS.
>> MOURNERS AT THE U.S. CAPITAL
FRIDAY NIGHT AT A VIGIL.
NOWHERE IS THE SADNESS MORE
PALPABLE THAN IN THIS SMALL
COMMUNITY.
>> REALLY STRUGGLE TO FIND THE
WORDS AS TO WHAT HAPPENED.
>> EVEN AN EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT
OBAMA HAD TO FIGHT BACK TEARS.
>> THIS EVENING MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT
IN AMERICA WILL DO WHICH IS HUG
OUR CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER,
AND WE WILL TELL THEM THAT WE
LOVE THEM AND WE WILL REMIND
EACH OTHER HOW DEEPLY WE LOVE
ONE ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT.
AND THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT
NOW.
>> ONE OF THE SIX ADULTS KILLED
WAS 47-YEAR-OLD DAWN HOCHSPRUNG
THE SCHOOL'S PRINCIPAL.
FORMER COLLEAGUES SAY SHE WAS
KNOWN FOR HER PLAYFUL PASSION.
JUST A MONTH AGO SHE DRESSED UP
AS THE SANDY HOOK BOOK FAIRY
WEARING A CROWN AND A DRESS THAT
LIGHTED UP TO INSPIRE FIRST
GRADERS TO READ.
NUMEROUS RELATIVES OF THE GUNMAN
ADAM LANZA INCLUDING HIS BROTHER
RYAN AND FATHER PETER.
POLICE SAY THE SHOOTING SPREE
BEGAN BY SHOOTING HIS MOTHER IF
HE FAMILY HOME AND LEFT WITH TWO
WE ARE LEARNING THREE GUNS ONE
OF THEM A RIFLE.
THE NEW YORK TIMES REPORTS HE
FIRED WITH CHILLING ACCURACY
LEAVING ONLY ONE WOUNDED
SURVIVOR AT THE SCHOOL.
AUTHORITIES BELIEVE HE THEN SHOT
HIMSELF TO DEATH.
ABC NEWS LEARNED BOTH OF HIS
PARENTS LEGALLY OWNED A NUMBER
OF GUNS INCLUDING A BUSHMASTER
RIFLE AND WE ARE JUST NOW
LEARNING THROUGH THE ASSOCIATED
PRESS THAT THE WEAPONS USED
WEREN'T REGISTERED TO LANZA'S
MOTHER.
A SCHOOL BUS DRIVER WHO KNEW
LANZA SAID IT WAS TOTALLY
UNEXPECTED.
>> THEY ARE NICE KIDS.
POLITE.
SHE RAISED VERY NICE BOYS TO ME.
THAT'S WHY I THINK IT'S A SHOCK
TO EVEN KNOW THEM AND REALIZE
WHO THEY ARE AND WHAT HE DID.
>>> WHEN ONE TEACHER HEARD GUN
FIRE SHE RACED TO HERD HER 15
STUDENTS INTO A TINY BATHROOM.
A QUICK THINKING FRANTIC EFFORT
TO SAVE THEIR YOUNG LIVES.
LISTEN AS SHE DESCRIBES WHAT
HAPPENED.
>> ONE OF MY STUDENTS ON TOP OF
THE TOILET.
I KNEW WE HAD TO GET IN THERE
AND TELLING THEM IT'S GOING TO
BE OKAY.
YOU ARE GOING TO BE ALL RIGHT.
I HAD PULLED THE BOOK SHELF
BEFORE I CLOSED THE DOOR IN
FRONT OF IT.
WE WERE COMPLETELY BARRICADED
IN.
I TURNED THE LIGHTS OFF.
I WAS AFRAID IF HE CAME IN HE
WOULD HEAR US HE WOULD START
SHOOTING THE DOOR.
I SAID WE NEED TO BE ABSOLUTELY
QUIET.
I SAID THERE ARE BAD GUYS OUT
THERE NOW AND WE NEED TO WAIT
FOR THE GOOD GUYS.
I AM HEARING THE GUN FIRE IN THE
HALLWAY.
I AM THINKING IN MY MIND I AM
THE FIRST CLASSROOM.
WHY ISN'T HE COMING.
I AM THINKING AS A 6-YEAR-OLD,
7-YEAR-OLD WHAT ARE YOUR
THOUGHTS, WHAT ARE YOUR -- I AM
THINKING THAT I HAVE TO ALMOST
BE THE PARENT, LIKE I HAVE TO
TELL THEM, YOU KNOW -- I SAID TO
THEM, I NEED YOU TO KNOW THAT I
LOVE YOU ALL VERY MUCH.
AND THAT IT IS GOING TO BE OKAY.
I THOUGHT IT WAS THE LAST THING
THEY WERE EVER GOING TO HEAR.
I THOUGHT WE WERE ALL GOING TO
DIE.
YOU KNOW, I DON'T KNOW IF THAT'S
OKAY -- TEACHERS AND -- I WANTED
THEM TO KNOW SOMEONE LOVES THEM
AND I WANTED THAT TO BE ONE OF
THE LAST THINGS THEY HEARD NOT
THE GUN FIRE IN THE HALLWAY.
>> 20/20 ANG KWOER CHRIS CUOMO
SPOKE TO PARENTS AS THEY RUSHED
TO THE SCHOOL.
>> SHE TALKS ABOUT THE HEROIC
ACTIONS OF HER TEACHER.
>> WHAT DO YOU REMEMBER?
WHAT HAPPENED?
>> WE GOT TO SCHOOL AND DID
EVERYTHING WE NEEDED TO AND THEN
WE HEARD THIS RACKET AT A
CLASSROOM.
WE WERE ALL SCARED.
THEN WE HEARD THEM SAY GO IN
YOUR CUBBIES.
>> EVERYBODY WENT TO THEIR
CUBBIES?
>> UH-HUH.
>> DID YOU HEAR ANY MORE BAD
NOISES?
>> YES.
>> WHILE THAT WAS GOING ON YOUR
TEACHER WAS READING YOU BOOKS
AND KEEPING YOU CALM?
>> YEAH.
>> YOU HAVE A GOOD TEACHER DON'T
YOU?
>> UH-HUH.
>> YOU LOVE YOUR TEACHER?
>> YES.
>> DID YOUR TEACHER SEEM
NERVOUS?
>> NO.
>> SHE JUST KEPT HER CALM AND
TOLD YOU A STORY.
>> UH-HUH.
>> YOU REMEMBER WHICH ONE?
>> SHE READ US THE NUT CRACKER
AND ANOTHER BOOK THAT WAS ABOUT
CHRISTMAS.
>> I LOVE THE NUT CRACKER.
DO YOU LOVE IT?
>> YES.
>> I AM AFRAID OF THE MOUSE
KING.
ILL SCARY.
LET'S BE HONEST, RIGHT?
NOT JUST ME.
YOU ARE IN THERE, HOW DO YOU
LEAVE THE CLASSROOM?
>> WE GOT IN A LINE AND WE HAD
OUR CLOSE OUR EYES.
>> YOU HAD TO CLOSE YOUR EYES?
>> YES.
>> AND WHEN YOU OPENED THEM
WHERE WERE YOU?
>> WE WERE WALKING DOWN TO THE
FIRE STATION.
>> WHAT HAPPENED THERE TODAY
HAPPENED, AND IT'S OVER.
OKAY?
YOU HAVE TO BE HAPPY THAT YOU
ARE OKAY.
ARE YOU OKAY?
I DIDN'T EVEN CHECK YOU OUT.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT.
WHAT HAPPENED HERE IN THE FRONT?
DID YOU HAVE TEETH HERE THIS
MORNING WHEN YOU WENT THERE?
>> NO.
>> ALL RIGHT.
YOU KNOW YOU ARE MISSING ALL OF
THE TEETH IN FRONT.
YOU ARE AWARE OF THAT?
CHRISTMAS LIST MATED?
>> UH-HUH.
>> SENT TO SANTA?
>> YES.
>> HOW LONG IS THE LIST?
>> 2 PIECES OF PAPER.
>> THAT WAS ABC'S CHRIS CUOMO
REPORTING.
HERE IN THE BAY AREA SMALL
GROUPS OF PEOPLE ARE CREATING
VIGILS TO REMEMBER THE VICTIMS.
ABC 7 NEWS REPORTER IS LIVE IN
GOLDEN GATE PARK WITH MORE ON
ONE THAT IS PLANNED FOR THIS
MORNING.
>> KATIE, A GROUP CALLED FAITH
STUDIO IS SPONSORING THE VIGIL
HERE AT THE AIDS MEMORIAL GROVE
IN GOLDEN GATE PARK.
THE PUBLIC IS WELCOME.
IT IS SET FOR 8:00 A.M.  AS YOU
CAN IMAGE IT'S NOT THE FIRST
TIME BAY AREA RESIDENTS ARE
GATHERING TO HONOR AND REMEMBER
THOSE WHO DIED.
LAST NIGHT IN MILL VALLEY 20
PEOPLE GATHERED IN SORROW.
PEOPLE OF ALL AGES REMEMBERED
THE 27 PEOPLE LOST TO SUCH
BRAZEN VIOLENCE.
WE SPOKE TO ONE SOPHOMORE WHO
CAME TO GRIEVE.
SHE SAID SHE CAME TO ACTAKE
ACTION.
SHE AND OTHER STUDENTS CAN FEEL
SAFE IN SCHOOL ONCE AGAIN.
>> IT IS IMPORTANT TO COME
TOGETHER IN MOMENTS LIKE THIS.
THIS SHOULDN'T BE WHAT HAPPENS
HERE.
THIS IS- -- WE SHOULD BE ABLE TO
LIVE IN A SAFE PLACE AND BE ABLE
TO WALK OUR STREETS AND BE A
COMMUNITY WITHOUT HAVING TO
WORRY FOR OUR LIVES, AND THIS
SHOULD NEVER, EVER HAPPEN.
>>> AND ACROSS THE BAY IN WALNUT
CREEK TWO DOZEN MOURNERS
GATHERED.
PARENTS BROUGHT THEIR ELEMENTARY
AGED SCHOOL CHILDREN IN HOPES OF
GETTING THEM TO UNDERSTAND WHAT
THE FAMILIES IN CONNECTICUT ARE
GOING THROUGH.
AGAIN HERE IN JUST ABOUT AN HOUR
AND A HALF THIS MORNING A VIGIL
IS PLANNED IN GOLDEN GATE PARK
AT THE AIDS MEMORIAL GROVE.
IT IS UNCLEAR HOW MANY PEOPLE
WILL ATTEND BUT THE PUBLIC IS
WELCOME AND ENCOURAGED TO COME.
REPORTING LIVE KIERRA CLAPPER
ABC 7 NEWS.
>> THANK YOU, KIERRA.
OFFICIALS ACROSS THE AREA FROM
FIELDING CALLS FROM CONCERNED
PARENTS.
A FEW PARENTS TOOK THEIR KIDS
HOME.
MANY SCHOOL DISTRICTS ALSO SENT
A LETTER HOME TO REASSURE
PARENTS THEIR CHILDREN ARE SAFE
AT SCHOOL.
ABC NEWS REPORTER ALLEN WONG HAS
MORE FROM OAKLAND.
>> AS NEWS OF THE TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT SPREAD, SO DID A
SENSE OF INSECURITY IN SCHOOLS
ACROSS THE BAY AREA.
>> IT REMINDED ME TO APPRECIATE
WHAT I HAVE AND TO DRAW MY LOVED
ONES CLOSER.
>> IN OAKLAND CITY POLICE
OFFICERS WERE AVAILABLE FOR ANY
SCHOOLS TO OFFER SAFETY ADVICE
AND A SENSE OF REASSURANCE.
>> IT IS TOTALLY WRONG.
BECAUSE LIKE THEY ARE KILLING
LITTLE KIDS.
>> IN UNION CITY THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT WILL HAVE THE FIRST
EVER ACTIVE SHOOTER DRILL NEXT
MARCH.
OFFICIALS ARE KEENLY AWARE OF
HOW THIS TRAGEDY MIGHT AFFECT
YOUNGER STUDENTS.
>> WITH YOUNGER CHILDREN IT'S A
FIRE DRILL LIKE EARTHQUAKE DRILL
LIKE MANEUVER WHERE YOU ARE
REASSURING YOUR CHILDREN AND
MOVING THE CHILDREN AROUND.
>> DISTRICT PSYCHOLOGISTS WERE
COACHING FACULTY MEMBERS ON HOW
TO SPOT SIGNS OF DISTRESS IN
KIDS AND HOW TO RESPOND WHEN
THEY COME BACK NEXT WEEK.
>> LET THEM KNOW EVERY ONCE IN A
WHILE THIS KIND OF THING DOES
HAPPEN BUT IT RARELY HAPPENS AND
THERE ARE ADULTS THERE THAT THEY
CAN GO TO WHEN THEY ARE FEELING
AFRAID.
>> IN SAN FRANCISCO IT WAS GUT
CHECK TIME.
SCHOOL OFFICIALS WERE
REEXAMINING SAFETY PLANS THAT
HAVE BEEN IN PLACE SINCE THE
COLUMBINE MASSACRE.
SINCE THEN POLICE SAY THE
TACTICS HAVE CHANGED.
>> WE TAKE IMMEDIATE ACTION.
WE KNOW LIVES ARE AT STAKE AND
IF THERE'S AN MEDIACY OUR
OFFICERS ARE TOLD TO GATHER AND
ENGAGE.
>> I AM ALLEN WONG, ABC 7 NEWS.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA IS USING HIS
WEEKLY ADDRESS TO ASK ALL
AMERICANS TO KEEP THE VICTIMS
AND VIOLENCE IN MIND.
>> AS A NATION WE HAVE ENDURED
FAR TOO MANY OF THESE TRAGEDIES
IN THE LAST FEW YEARS.
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
SHOPPING MALL IN OREGON, HOUSE
OF WORSHIP IN WISCONSIN, A MOVIE
THEATER IN COLORADO, COUNTLESS
STREET CORNERS IN PLACES LIKE
CHICAGO AND PHILADELPHIA.
ANY OF THESE NEIGHBORHOODS COULD
BE OUR OWN.
WE HAVE TO COME TOGETHER AND WE
ARE GOING TO HAVE TO TAKE
MEANINGFUL ACTION TO PREVENT
MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS FROM
HAPPENING.
>>> THE PRESIDENT ASKED EACH
AMERICAN TO EXTEND A HAND TO
FAMILIES IN THEIR OWN
COMMUNITIES WHO HAVE LOST LOVED
ONES TO VIOLENCE.
AS DEVELOPMENTS CONTINUE TO
UNFOLD IN CONNECTICUT YOU CAN
RECEIVE URGENT UPDATES BY
DOWNLOADING THE FREE ABC 7 NEWS
SMART PHONE APP.
YOU SHOULD OPT FOR THE PUSH
NOTIFICATIONS.
WE HAVE UPDATES ON TWITTER AS
WELL.
PLEASE FOLLOW ON NEWS BAY AREA
AND THE WEB TEAM IS SENDING OUT
UPDATES AS WELL.
YOU CAN SIGN UP FOR THE BREAKING
NEWS LETTER AT ABC7NEWS.COM.
>>> UP NEXT, NEW CALLS FOR GUN
CONTROL AS PEOPLE STRUGGLE WITH
THE TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT
OTHERS ARE THINK BEING HOW TO
PREVENT IT FROM HAPPENING AGAIN.
THE SCENE IN CONNECTICUT IS ALL
TOO FAMILIAR IN COLUMBINE,
COLORADO.
RESIDENTS THERE ARE REACHING OUT
TO PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN.
OUR COVERAGE OF THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT CONTINUES
IN JUST A MOMENT.oducing NOOK H-
the world's best 7" tablet made
for reading and entertainment.
Your favorite magazines and
catalogs look better than ever.
And with scrapbooking,
you can save the
things you love,
bring them all together,
And be inspired like
never before.
Scrapbooking. Create
yours with Nook HD -
and even bigger with HD+.
Find yours at Barnes & Noble.
>> GUN CONTROL IS BEING DEBATED
AFTER THE TRAGIC SCHOOL SHOOTING
IN CONNECTICUT.
TAUS A CONVERSATION TAKING PLACE
IN THE NATION'S CAPITOL AND HERE
AT HOME.
>> PLEASE LAYOUT A PLAN OF
ACTION ON HOW WE CAN ADDRESS THE
GUN VIOLENCE IN OUR COMMUNITY.
>> THE SCHOOL SHOOTING GAVE RISE
TO AN ANTI GUN RALLY.
IN CALIFORNIA WE HAVE THE
STRONGEST GUN LAWS IN THE
COUNTRY AS BY THE BRADY CAMPAIGN
TO PREVENT GUN VIOLENCE.
>> THEY HAVE THEEST FATALITY
RATES OF GUN FIRE IN THE NATION.
>> THEY ARE CONSIDERING
REINTRODUCING A BILL THAT CLOSES
THE LOOPHOLE IN ASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN.
THEY ARE IN FAVOR OF MORE
RESTRICTIONS.
HE SAYS THE CURRENT LAWS ARE
FINE.
>> ISOLATED INCIDENTS IT'S
TRAGIC BUT WE CAN'T KNEE JERK
AND THINK THAT'S GOING TO SOLVE
THE PROBLEM.
IT'S REALLY NOT.
THEY ARE WANTING TO DO SOMETHING
BAD THEY ARE GOING TO FIGURE OUT
A WAY TO DO IT.
>> OTHERS FEEL SOMETHING NEEDS
TO CHANGE.
>> JUST WATCHING THE PREVALENCE
OF GUN VIOLENCE IN OUR SOCIETY I
CAN'T STAND BY AND WATCH THAT.
>> NEED TO LOOK INSIDE THE
MIRROR AND TAKE A LOOK AND
REALIZE WE CHANGE A FEW THINGS
HOW WE DEAL WITH GUNS AND THE
WAY WE ISSUE SOCIETY AS WELL AS
HOW WE ENCOURAGE VIOLENCE IN
SOCIETY.
>> HE IS REPORTING WE HAVE NOT
HEARD ANY.
FACEBOOK PAGE WAS UNAVAILABLE
MOST OF YESTERDAY.
YOU WILL REMEMBER THIS DAY
APRIL 20TH, 1999.
THE NATION WAS HORRIFIED WITH
TELEVISION IMAGES OF HIGH SCHOOL
STUDENTS RUNNING FOR THEIR LIVES
AT COLUMBINE HIGH SCHOOL IN
DENVER.
TWO STUDENTS SHOT OTHER STUDENTS
AND ONE TEACHER KILLING THEM
INJURING 21 OTHERS BEFORE
FATALLY SHOOTING THEMSELVES.
THE PRINCIPAL OF COLUMBINE IS
STILL THE PRINCIPAL TODAY.
>> MY ADVICE TO THEM IS THEY ARE
NOT IN THIS ALONE.
>> DENVER NOW HAS DETAILED
DIAGRAMS FOR ALL OF THE SCHOOLS
AND HAS TAKEN STEPS TO LIMIT
ACCESS POINTS FOR BETTER
SECURITY.
HE DOES NOT THINK GUN CONTROL OR
TOUGHER LAW ALSO NOT PREVENT
MASS KILLINGS.
WE HAVE THE FORECAST WHICH WE
NEED TO KEEP A CLOSE EYE ON.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
WE HAVE LIGHT RAIN HEADED OUR
WAY.
RIGHT NOW DRY AND COLD.
IN FACT FROM OUR EAST BAY CAMERA
YOU CAN SEE THE PRETTY CLOUDS
OUT THERE.
THE AREAS AT PRODUCING
TEMPERATURES WELL BELOW FREEZING
IN SOME SPOTS.
I WILL EXPLAIN AND WHEN THE RAIN
ARRIVES NEXT COMING UP.
>> THANK YOU, LISA.
BAY AREA STUDENTS WRITE LETTERS
TO SANTA.
THEY ARE NOT ASKING WHAT THEY
WANT FOR CHRISTMAS THE LETTERS
a little rendezvous.♪
♪That special something that
will carry you through...♪
♪that little reward for
all the things you do.♪
Luscious, creamy filling -
combined with our slow
melting chocolate -
B
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT A LITTLE
BIT OF SNOW.
LOW SNOW LEVELS FOR THE
FOOTHILLS BUT NOT A LOT OF
ACCUMULATION.
THEY CAN MAKE THE SNOW AND IT
WILL BE STAYING THERE BECAUSE WE
ARE LOOKING AT VERY CHILLY
SYSTEMS TO HEAD OUR WAY IN THE
NEXT SEVERAL DAYS.
A LOOK FROM OUR CAMERA YOU CAN
SEE THE CLOUDS IN PARTS OF SAN
FRANCISCO.
NUMBERS IN THE 40s.
LIVE DOPPLER 7 H. D. AND WE HAVE
LIGHT RAIN THAT IS OFF THE COAST
AND MAINLY TO THE NORTH AND WEST
OF US.
IT IS A WEAK SYSTEM THAT WILL
CONTINUE TO DEVELOP AND SPREAD
LIGHT RAIN OUR WAY THROUGH OUT
THE MIDDAY AND THE NORTH BAY.
LATER IN THE AFTERNOON PARTS OF
THE SOUTH BAY ON THE WEST SIDE
TOMORROW.
36 DEGREES FROM THE CITY.
41 FOR YOU FREMONT.
41 BY THE DELTA.
YOU ARE AT 29 LAST HOUR FY
FAIRFIELD.
IT IS FREEZING WITH FOG IN SANTA
ROSA AND FREEZING IN LIVERMORE
WITH QUARTER MILE VISIBILITY
THERE.
LESS THAN THAT IN NAVADO.
BETTER VISIBILITY BUT YOU HAVE
THE TRADE-OFF WITH PARTLY CLOUDY
SKIES AND FREEZING CONDITIONS
AROUND THE AREAS THAT HAVE THE
CLEAR CONDITIONS.
IN THE 30s IN SAN JOSE WELL.
COLD AND CHILLY.
TEMPERATURES LIGHT RAIN
DEVELOPING.
WE LOOK FOR THE CHANCE OF
SHOWERS THROUGH THE NORTH BAY
MAINLY TOMORROW.
YOU WILL HAVE A FEW LIGHT
RAINSHOWERS AROUND.
NEXT SYSTEM HEADS OUR WAY
MONDAY.
THIS LOOKS LIKE A LITTLE WETTER
SYSTEM.
YOU WILL NOTICE THAT THE CLOUDS
ARE TO THE NORTH OF US.
THEY WILL SINK TO THE SOUTH AND
NOT BRINGING A LOT OF RADIATION.
UNDER THE CLOUDS WE ARE LOOKING
AT LIGHT RAIN.
HERE'S THE TIMING OF IT AS WE GO
THROUGH THE MORNING HOURS PARTS
OF THE NORTH BAY LOOKING WET.
TEMPERATURES ONLY IN THE 40s.
>> LISA, THANK YOU.
AS THE TRAGEDY CONTINUES TO
UNFOLD IN CONNECTICUT IT IS GOOD
TO REMIND US THERE IS GOOD IN
THE WORLD.
WE SHARE A STORY OF HOPE AND
LOVE.
STUDENTS WROTE LETTERS TO SANTA
ASKING HIM TO GRANT A WISH TO
KICK SIDS AS PART OF THE MAKE A
WISH CAMPAIGN.
LEEANN MENDEZ HAS THIS STORY.
>> HOW MANY LETTERS DID OUR
SECOND GRADERS HERE.
>> THIS IS ONLY A FEW OF THE
THOUSANDS OF KIDS IN FREMONT WHO
WROTE A WISH ON A PIECE OF
PAPER.
>> I WISHED ABOUT MY FAMILY AND
FRIENDS THAT MY MOM AND DAD HAVE
A GREAT TIME IN THEIR LIFE AND
TO NOT HAVE TO HAVE TROUBLE WITH
IT.
>> CHILDREN STAY OUT OF THE
HOSPITAL AND STFEELING BETTER
ABOUT THEMSELVES BEING OUT.
>> THE TEACHERS ORGANIZED THE
PRODUCT.
>> IT CAN BE PEOPLE CLOSE TO
THEM OR CHILDREN FROM MAKE A
WISH.
IT COULD BE SOME OF THE KIDS
READ ABOUT WHAT THEY WISH FOR
FOR OBAMA.
>> FOR EACH LETTER MACY'S
DONATED $2 TO MAKE A WISH
FOUNDATION.
THEY HAVE LIFE THREATENING
MEDICAL CONDITIONS LIKE SHELBY.
SHE ARRIVED IN A LIMO AND HAD A
SHOPPING SPREE AT WALNUT CREEK
TODAY BEFORE LYING OFF IN
JANUARY TO MEET JUSTIN BIEBER.
STUDENTS FROM THE FREMONT SCHOOL
DISTRICT AND PARENTS IMAGED TO
WRITE MORE THAN 41,000 LETTERS.
>> SOMETIMES WHEN I DO IT I AM
HURT B
-- MY HANDS HURT BUT I KEEP ON
DOING IT.
>> THEY RECEIVE 80,000 DOLLARS
WHICH WILL BE SPENT ON GRANTING
WISHES TO ABOUT 8 BIG CHILDREN.
>> IF YOU ARE IN PAIN YOU DON'T
HAVE MUCH TO DO YOU CAN'T GO OUT
ANYWHERE.
>> WE WANT OUR KIDS TO LEARN TO
PAY IT FORWARD, TO THINK OF
OTHERS FIRST.
AND PLUS WE ARE GETTING THEM TO
WRITE.
>> HE TOLD US HIS BABY SISTER
HAD BEEN SICK.
HE MENTIONED HER IN HIS LETTER.
>> I HOPE SHE GETS BETTER.
>> SHE IS BETTER NOW.
>> THE POWER OF BELIEVING.
IN FREMONT LEEANN MELENDEZ, ABC
7 NEWS.
>> WE WILL BE BACK WITH MORE
[ Female Announcer ]
What would you call
an ordinary breakfast pastry
that's been wrapped
in a flaky crust
stuffed with a gooey center
toasted up all golden brown
then given a delicious design?
A toaster strudel.
Pillsbury Toaster Strudel.
So Delicious...So Fun.
FASTER THAN MANDY CAN HANG UP
ON MR. MONDAY.
YOU HANG UP FIRST.
[ Female Announcer ]
IN JUST 60 SECONDS, YOU'VE GOT
SNACK-DEFYING, SATISFYING
TOTINO'S PIZZA ROLLS.
[ ringing ]
IT'S ON. LET'S ROLL.
>> THE VICTIMS HAVE BEEN
IDENTIFIED.
IT IS NOT CLEAR IF THE NAMES
WILL BE RELEASED.
27 VICTIMS.
20 CHILDREN.
THE MOTHER NANCY LANZA OF THE
SHOOTER IS ONE OF THEM.
THERE IS NO RECORDS SHE WORKS
FOR THE SCHOOLS.
SHE MAY HAVE BEEN A VOLUNTEER OR
A SUBSTITUTE.
WE ARE LEARNING THIS MORNING THE
SHOOTER ADAM LANZA BROUGHT THREE
GUNS INTO THE SCHOOL AND THE
WEAPONS ARE REGISTERED TO HIS
MOTHER.
ABC NEWS REPORTS LANZA GAYE
ACCESS TO THE SCHOOL BY BREAKING
A GLASS WINDOW NEAR THE FRONT
DOOR.
YOU CAN EXPRESS CONDOLENCES TO
THOSE TOUCHED BY THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY ON FACEBOOK PAGE.
WE INVITE YOU TO SHARE YOUR
THOUGHTS AT FACEBOOK.COM/ABC 7
NEWS.
YOU CAN POST THIS BADGE TO YOUR
FACEBOOK WALL FOR A SILENT SHOW
OF SUPPORT TO EVERYONE AT
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US ON THE
ABC 7 SATURDAY MORNING NEWS.
ABC 7 NEWS CONTINUES AT
8:00 A.M.  GO"GOOD MORNING
>>> EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY
TODAY.
>> GOOD MORNING, AMERICA.
THIS MORNING, TRAGEDY AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> I ACTUALLY PRAYED TO GOD.
>> NEW DETAILS UNFOLD OVERNIGHT
ABOUT THIS HORRIFIC CRIME.
SO HARD TO COMPREHEND.
>> WE WERE LIKE ALL SCARED.
>> 27 DEAD.
MOST OF THEM CHILDREN.
THE PRINCIPAL GUNNED DOWN.
AND BREAKING, NEW INFORMATION
THIS MORNING ABOUT THE SHOOTER.
>> IT WAS TERRIFYING.