ANGELS.
>> I WANT EVERYBODY TO KNOW WHAT
A SPECIAL LITTLE GIRL SHE WAS.
>> AS A NATION JOINS TOGETHER TO
PRAY AND PREVENT MORE KILLING,
BREAKING NEW DETAILS EMERGE
ABOUT THE GUNMAN, HIS MYSTERIOUS
CONDITION, AND HIS UNSPEAKABLE
VIOLENCE.
WHAT WILL IT TAKE?
WHAT CAN WE DO?
AMERICA'S SEARCH FOR ANSWERS, A
NATIONAL CONVERSATION, STARTS
RIGHT NOW ON "GMA."
>>> AND EVERYTHING HERE IS
STILL SO RAW.
HERE THIS MORNING.
THE COMMUNITY COMING TOGETHER.
PUTTING TOGETHER THOSE LIVING
MENT
MEMORIALS TOGETHER.
A TOWN IN TEARS BUT ALSO A TOWN
GALVANIZED BY THEIR GRIEF.
GOOD MORNING, AMERICA, FROM
SANDY HOOK.
I'M JOINED BY JOSH AND AMY AND
LARA.
LIZ INTET IN NEW YORK.
RIGHT NOW, ALL ACROSS AMERICA,
PARENTS ARE SENDING THEIR
CHILDREN TO SCHOOL, A LOT OF
FEAR AS WELL.
WE WANT TO BEGIN WITH GUN
VIOLENCE, MENTAL ILLNESS.
WE'LL CONTINUE IT ALL WEEK LONG.
>> ARE MY CHILDREN SAFE,
IT'S A QUESTION PARENTS ARE
ASKING.
SECURITY HAS BEEN BEEFED UP AT
SCHOOLS AND CAMPUSES AROUND THE
COUNTRY.
AS NEW DETAILS NOW SURFACE ABOUT
THE HORRIFYING MOMENTS WHEN THE
SHOOTER ENTERED THAT SCHOOL AND
UNIMAGINABLE.
TO END THAT, WE'LL BE JOINED BY
THE SCHOOL NURSE.
>> SALLY COX.
SHE'LL BE WITH US IN A MINUTE.
>>> LET'S GET RIGHT TO THE
PRESIDENTS RIGHT NOW.
HE SPOKE LAST NIGHT.
HE CAME HERE AND MET WITH THE
FAMILIES.
HE WAS WITH ALLISON, THE
GRANDDAUGHTER OF THE SCHOOL
PRINCIPAL.
THE PRESIDENT COMFORTED THE
FAMILIES YESTERDAY.
THEN DELIVERED THE SPEECH.
HE TOLD THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN,
THEY'RE NOT ALONE.
A POWERFUL CALL TO ACTION.
A PRESIDENT FILLED WITH ANGRY.
>> I COME TO OFFER THE LOVE AND
PRAYERS OF A NATION.
MERE WORDS CANNOT MATCH THE
DEPTHS OF YOUR SORROW.
NOR CAN THEY HEAL YOUR WOUNDED
HEARTS.
YOU'RE NOT ALONE IN YOUR GRIEF.
>> Reporter: CONSOLATION FIRST.
AND THEN, A CALL TO ACTION.
>> THIS IS OUR FIRST TASK.
CARING FOR OUR CHILDREN.
IF WE DON'T GET THAT RIGHT, WE
DON'T GET ANYTHING RIGHT.
CAN WE TRULY SAY, AS A NATION,
THAT WE'RE MEETING OUR
OBLIGATIONS?
THE ANSWER IS NO.
THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
AND TO END THEM, WE MUST CHANGE.
>> Reporter: PRESIDENT OBAMA,
STRICKEN AND STERN, PROMISED TO
MAKE AMERICA SAFER FOR OUR
CHILDREN.
>> I'LL USE WHATEVER POWER THIS
OFFICE HOLDS TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW
CITIZENS IN AN EFFORT AIMED AT
PREVENTING MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE
THIS.
ARE WE REALLY PREPARED TO SAY
WE'RE POWERLESS IN THE FACE OF
SUCH CARNAGE?
>> Reporter: ACROSS THE
AUDIENCE, TEARS BECAME SOBS, AS
THE PRESIDENT REMEMBERED THOSE
WHO SHIELDED THE CHILDREN.
>> DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, MARY
SHERLACH, LAUREN ROUSSEAU, VICKI
SOTO, RACHEL DAVINO AND ANNE
MARIE MURPHY.
>> Reporter: AND FINALLY, ONE BY
ONE, EACH OF THE 20 LITTLE ONES.
LIVES CUT SHORT IN THE FIRST
GRADE.
>> CHARLOTTE.
DANIEL.
OLIVIA.
JOSEPHINE.
ANA.
DYLAN, MADELEINE, CATHERINE.
CHASE.
JESSE.
JAMES.
GRACE.
EMILIE.
JACK.
NOAH.
CAROLINE.
JESSICA.
BENJAMIN.
AVIELLE.
ALLISON.
>> Reporter: A PRESIDENT'S
TRIBUTE, OFFERING COMFORT TO THE
FAMILIES, ENCOURAGEMENT TO
NEWTOWN, AND A CHALLENGE FOR ALL
OF US.
AND THE FIRST TWO OF THOSE
YOUNG VICTIMS WILL BE LAID TO
REST TODAY.
NOAH POZNER AND JACK PINTO.
AMY, YOU'VE SPENT THE WEEKEND
MEETING WITH THE FAMILIES AND
SHARING THEIR PAIN.
>> IT'S BEEN INCREDIBLY
DIFFICULT.
I HAVE REALIZED IT'S SO
IMPORTANT FOR MANY OF THESE
FAMILIES THAT THEIR CHILDREN AND
LOVED ONES ARE NOT FORGOTTEN.
THEY WANT PEOPLE ACROSS THE
COUNTRY TO KNOW THEIR NAMES,
TO REMEMBER THEIR FACES, AND
REMEMBER HOW THEY LIVED.
♪
THESE ARE THE FACES OF
INNOCENCE.
12 BRIGHT-EYED GIRLS AND 8 BOYS
WHO HAD SO MUCH LIVING LEFT TO
DO.
6-YEAR-OLD EMILIE PARKER WAS A
BIG SISTER.
SHE LOVED TO DRAW AND ALWAYS
CARRIED HER MARKERS AND PENCILS.
HER FATHER WAS TEACHING HER HOW
TO SPEAK PORTUGUESE.
>> THE EXAMPLE SHE SHOWED US IS
REMARKABLE.
SHE'S AN INCREDIBLE PERSON.
I'M SO BLESSED TO BE HER DAD.
>> Reporter: NOAH POZNER AND HIS
TWIN SISTER CELEBRATED THEIR 6th
BIRTHDAY LAST MONTH.
SHE SURVIVED THE SHOOTING.
BUT LITTLE NOAH DID NOT.
THE FAMILY OF 7-YEAR-OLD GRACE
McDONNELL TELLS US OUR DAUGHTER
GRACE WAS THE LOVE AND THE LIGHT
OF OUR FAMILY.
WORDS CANNOT EXPRESS OUR SENSE
OF LOSS.
6-YEAR-OLD ANA MARQUEZ-GREENE
JUST MOVED TO NEWTON FROM
CANADA.
HERE SHE IS SINGING AND PLAYING
THE PIANO WITH HER BROTHER.
♪ COME NOW ALMIGHTY KING HELP US
GUIDE ♪
>> Reporter: CATHERINE HUBBARD
WAS 6 YEARS OLD AND THE NIECE OF
AN ABC EMPLOYEE.
HER FAMILY SAID IN A STATEMENT
SATURDAY -- WE ASK THAT YOU
CONTINUE TO PRAY FOR US.
THE FAMILY OF 6-YEAR-OLD OLIVIA
ENGEL TELLS US SHE LOVED SCHOOL
AND WAS GOOD AT MATH AND
READING.
HER PHYSICAL LOSS WILL BE FELT
EVERY DAY BE EVERYONE WHO LOVED
HER MOST.
HER SPIRIT WILL LIVE ON.
6-YEAR-OLD JESSE LEWIS WAS
LOOKING FORWARD TO MAKING
GINGERBREAD HOUSES IN CLASS THAT
DAY.
HIS FATHER PLANNED TO JOIN HIM.
THEN THERE WAS
JESSICA REKOS, WHO WAS 6, HER
PARENTS SAID THEY WANTED TO
CREATE HAPPY MEMORIES FOR THEIR
CHILDREN.
>> JESSICA LOVED TO GO SANDY
HOOK, SUCH PRIDE BECAUSE HER DAD
WENT THERE, TOO.
>> NOW, I SAT DOWN WITH
JESSICA'S PARENTS YESTERDAY.
I'LL HAVE MORE OF THE INTERVIEW
COMING UP.
BUT I HAVE TO TELL YOU THIS
INTERVIEW IS SO POWERFUL.
IT LEFT SUCH AN IMPRESSION ON ME
AND THE ENTIRE CREW.
THERE WAS NOT A DRY EYE.
IT'S SOMETHING THAT YOU'LL NEVER
FORGET.
>> NOW TO ELIZABETH IN NEW YORK.
>> ALL RIGHT, GEORGE, THANK YOU
SO MUCH.
NEW DETAILS THIS MORNING ABOUT
THE GUNMAN.
WE'RE PIECING TOGETHER A PICTURE
OF ADAM LANZA.
BUT STILL LEFT WITH THE QUESTION
OF WHY HE WOULD COMMIT THIS
HORRIFIC ACT?
WHY WOULD HE TARGET SUCH SMALL
CHILDREN?
ABC'S CHIEF INVESTIGATIVE
REPORTER BRIAN ROSS HAS BEEN
TRACKING THAT PART OF THE STORY
SINCE THE BEGINNING.
WHAT HAVE YOU LEARNED?
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING,
ELIZABETH.
AUTHORITIES SAY THEY EXPECT MORE
PROGRESS TODAY AS THEY FIGURE
OUT THE HOW AND THE WHY OF WHAT
HAPPENED.
BUT EVEN VETERAN DETECTIVES AND
AGENTS ARE HAVING A HARD TIME AT
THE SCENE.
HE HAD A HUGE QUANTITY OF
BULLETS LEFT FOR HIS
HIGH-POWERED WEAPONS.
>> ALL WEAPONS HAVE MULTIPLE
MAGAZINES AND ADDITIONAL
AMMUNITION.
>> Reporter: AS TO HIS MOTIVE,
OFFICIALS TELL ABC NEWS THAT
COMPUTERS REMOVED FROM THE HOME
OVER THE WEEKEND PROVIDE
IMPORTANT CLUES TO HIS TWISTED
THINKING.
IT WAS HERE HE KILLED HIS FIRST
VICTIM, HIS MOTHER, 52-YEAR-OLD
NANCY LANZA, WHO FRIENDS SAID
HAD BECOME MORE AND MORE
CONCERNED ABOUT ADAM'S ISSUES
OVER THE LAST FEW MONTHS.
>> IT WAS HARDER FOR HER AS TIME
WENT ON, AS HE WAS GETTING
THROUGH SCHOOL.
>> Reporter: ADAM'S PARENTS WERE
DIVORCED THREE YEARS AGO.
HIS MOTHER WAS LEFT TO DEAL WITH
HIM ALONE, ACCORDING TO HER
FRIENDS.
>> SHE TOOK CARE OF HIM THE BEST
SHE COULD.
>> Reporter: SINCE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AT SANDY HOOK UNTIL HIS
MOTHER HOME-SCHOOLED HIM, ADAM
WAS KNOWN BY CLASSMATES AS ODD.
>> HE HATED TO LOOK INTO YOUR
EYES FOR MORE THAN A FEW
SECONDS.
>> Reporter: HE WAS A MEMBER OF
THE TECH CLUB.
AND THE SCHOOL'S FORMER SECURITY
DIRECTOR SAYS THE YOUNG MAN
COULD FEEL NEITHER EMOTIONAL NOR
PHYSICAL PAIN.
>> IF HE CUT HIMSELF OR HURT
HIMSELF, HE WOULD NOT KNOW IT OR
FEEL IT.
>> Reporter: HE SAYS LANZA HAD
SEVERAL DISORDERS AND WAS SEEING
THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST.
>> HE HAD PERIODS OF TIME WHERE
HE WOULD WITHDRAW ENTIRELY.
YOU WOULD HAVE TO WORK HARD TO
REACH HIM AGAIN.
>> Reporter: POLICE THIS MORNING
SAY WHEN HE KILLED HIS FIRST
VICTIM, HE USED THE
ASSAULT-STYLE RIFLE TO KILL HER
WITH SEVERAL SHOTS TO THE HEAD.
A GUN THAT SHE OWNED LEGALLY.
ELIZABETH.
>> AND YOUR EXPERT IN THE PIECE
SAYING HE DIDN'T FEEL PHYSICAL
PAIN.
MAKES YOU WONDER IF THAT MEANS
HE DIDN'T FEEL EMOTIONAL PAIN AS
WELL.
WE'LL BE DELVING INTO THAT IN
THE NEXT HALF HOUR.
BRIAN, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
LET'S GO BACK OUT TO SANDY HOOK
AND GEORGE.
>>> AS WE JUST HEARD FROM BRIAN,
THIS TRAGEDY COULD HAVE BEEN SO
MUCH WORSE.
THERE'S SO MANY HEROES EMERGING,
FROM THE TEACHERS TO THE FIRST
RESPONDERS.
LARA, YOU HAVE MET WITH A LOT OF
THEM.
>> I HAVE.
THIS MORNING,
WE'RE HEARING ABOUT THE
UNIMAGINABLE COURAGE THAT WENT
ON INSIDE THE SCHOOL ON FRIDAY.
ALL IN AN EFFORT TO PROTECT
THOSE CHILDREN.
THE INCREDIBLE INSTINCTS THAT
LED TO SACRIFICE AND SURVIVAL.
A CLEAR PICTURE HAS EMERGED OF
THE HEROES OF SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL.
IS THERE ANY WAY TO KNOW HOW
MANY LIVES SHE SAVED?
>> YOU KNOW, I DON'T KNOW
ACCURATELY.
I HEARD 14.
>> Reporter: LIKE THAT
27-YEAR-OLD FIRST GRADE TEACHER,
VICKI SOTO, WHO LOST HER OWN
LIFE PROTECTING HER STUDENTS
FROM THE GUNMAN
BY LOCKING THEM IN THE CLOSET
AND TELLING THE SHOOTER THEY
WERE IN THE OTHER SIDE OF THE
BUILDING.
DOES IT SURPRISE YOU SHE WAS
FOUND HUDDLED OVER THE KIDS?
>> NO.
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
>> Reporter: DAWN HOCHSPRUNG AND
MARY SHERLACH WERE KILLED AFTER
CONFRONTING THE GUNMAN.
>> THEY RESPONDED IN THE WAY WE
ALL HOPE WE MIGHT RESPOND.
IN TERRIFYING CIRCUMSTANCES.
>> Reporter: ALYSSA STONE WAS A
DEAR FRIEND OF
SPECIAL EDUCATION TEACHER
RACHEL DAVINO.
NOW ALYSSA HAS THE PAINFUL TASK
OF BURYING A FRIEND.
>> SHE WAS BRAVE AND CONFIDENT
AND WOULD BE THE FIRST PERSON TO
GET IN SOMEONE'S FACE.
>> Reporter: YOU THINK SHE GOT
IN HIS FACE?
>> I WOULD ASSUME SO.
IF SHE WAS -- SHE WAS A MOTHER
TIGER DEFENDING HER CUBS, I
WOULD PICTURE HER ACTING LIKE
THAT.
YEAH.
>> Reporter: NO STORY PERHAPS IS
MORE POIGNANT THAN THE LITTLE
6-YEAR-OLD GIRL WHO WAS THE ONLY
SURVIVOR IN HER CLASS OF 15
STUDENTS.
HER PASTOR JIM SOLOMON TELLS HER
STORY.
>> SHE, BEING SUCH AN
INTELLIGENT LITTLE GIRL, SOMEHOW
IN THAT MOMENT, BY GOD'S GRACE,
WAS ABLE TO ACT AS IF SHE WAS
ALREADY DECEASED.
SO THAT THE GUNMAN WOULDN'T
TARGET HER.
SO SHE LAID THERE PRETENDING SHE
WAS DEAD.
>>> AND WE'RE JOINED NOW BY
ANOTHER SURVIVOR OF THIS
TRAGEDY, THE SCHOOL NURSE, SALLY
COX.
THANK YOU FOR COMING IN THIS
MORNING.
>> THANK YOU.
>> I KNOW THIS IS DIFFICULT.
TAKE US BACK TO THAT MOMENT.
WHEN DID YOU FIRST KNOW
SOMETHING HAD GONE WRONG?
>> HEARING A LOUD POPPING NOISE.
I MEAN, JUST -- SOMETHING I HAVE
NEVER HEARD IN MY LIFE.
AND YOUR MIND DOESN'T THINK THAT
IT COULD BE THAT.
BUT WHEN THE SECRETARY CALLED
OUT TO ME, WITH TERROR IN HER
VOICE, IT JUST TOLD ME THERE WAS
SOMETHING TERRIBLE HAPPENING.
>> AND THAT'S WHEN YOU WENT
UNDER THE DESK?
>> MY COMPUTER DESK, YES.
>> WHILE YOU'RE UNDER THERE, YOU
ACTUALLY SEE THE FEET OF THE
SHOOTER?
>> THERE'S AN OPENING IN THE
BACK FOR WIRING.
AND, AS I WAS CROUCHING DOWN, I
COULD SEE MY DOORWAY, BECAUSE
YOU -- IN THE OFFICE, YOU ENTER
THE OFFICE AND THEN INTO MY
OFFICE.
AND WHEN I HEARD THE DOOR CLOSE,
YOU KNOW -- AND HE PROBABLY
WALKED IN, AND I WAS LOOKING AND
I SAW -- I COULD SEE HIM FROM
THE KNEES DOWN.
SEE THE LEGS.
>> RIGHT IN FRONT OF YOU?
>> 20 FEET AWAY.
HIS BOOTS WERE FACING MY DESK.
>> AND HE TURNED AND WALKED
AWAY?
>> IT WAS SECONDS.
HE TURNED AND WALKED OUT.
I HEARD THE DOOR CLOSE.
>> OKAY, SO THE DOOR CLOSES.
WHAT DO YOU DO NEXT?
>> AFTER THE DOOR CLOSED, I
DON'T KNOW HOW THE SECRETARY HAD
THE COURAGE, BUT SHE DID.
SHE RACED INTO MY OFFICE AND
PULLED THE DOOR CLOSED AND RACED
BEHIND MY DESK.
WE PULLED THE PHONE OFF MY DESK
AND I HELD THE PHONE WHILE SHE
DIALED 911.
WE PLACED A CALL.
>> THANK GOODNESS YOU DID THAT.
BECAUSE THE FACT THAT THE POLICE
GOT THERE SO QUICKLY, THE
GOVERNOR SAID, PREVENTED MORE
KILLING.
RIGHT AFTER THAT, YOU LOCKED
YOURSELF IN?
>> WE RACED INTO MY SUPPLY
CLOSET AND PULLED THE DOOR
CLOSED.
>> YOU WERE THERE FOR THE NEXT
FOUR HOURS.
>> NEARLY.
YEAH, YEAH.
IT WAS 1:15 BEFORE WE -- WE --
WE WERE PETRIFIED.
AND WE DIDN'T KNOW HOW MANY
THERE COULD HAVE BEEN.
WE WERE LISTENING.
YOU COULDN'T HEAR A WHOLE LOT.
BUT WE HEARD SCREAMING AND THE
GUNSHOTS.
AND --
>> I KNOW THE POLICE SHIELDED
YOU AS YOU LEFT.
SO YOU WOULDN'T SEE WHAT
HAPPENED.
>> RIGHT.
THEY TOLD US TO CLOSE OUR EYES.
THEY SAID, CLOSE YOUR EYES.
>> YOU KNEW EVERY CHILD IN THAT
SCHOOL.
>> I SEE THEM ALL AT LEAST ONCE
A YEAR FOR THEIR HEARING AND
VISION, SO -- YOU KNOW, AND
THEN, SOME I SEE A LOT MORE
OFTEN.
BUT I GET TO KNOW THEM.
>> I KNOW AT FIRST YOU DIDN'T
WANT TO HEAR ABOUT THE VICTIMS.
>> YEAH.
>> HAVE YOU BEEN ABLE TO LEARN
ANYTHING MORE SINCE?
>> OH, YEAH, BY SATURDAY NIGHT,
THE LIST WASN'T OFFICIALLY OUT
UNTIL -- THE PUBLIC UNTIL
SATURDAY NIGHT.
>> FINALLY, I KNOW YOU HAVE BEEN
STARTING TO LEARN THAT FOR NOW
AT LEAST YOU MAY NOT BE GOING
BACK TO SANDY HOOK.
HOW LONG WILL THAT BE?
>> THEY REALLY HAVEN'T GIVEN US
ANY INDICATION.
THERE'S A LOT OF DIFFERENT
THINGS BEING MENTIONED.
AND -- BUT WE KNOW THERE WILL BE
AT LEAST A TEMPORARY PLACE FOR
US TO GO.
>> AND NOT BACK TO THAT SCHOOL.
>> NOT BACK TO THAT SCHOOL, NO.
>> SALLY, THANK YOU FOR JOINING
US.
>> THANK YOU, THANK YOU.
JOSH?
>> GEORGE, EVEN AS THIS TOWN
CONTINUES TO STRUGGLE THERE'S
SO MUCH SUPPORT POURING IN FROM
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
CHILDREN AND PARENTS A NATION
OVER, LOOKING TO COMFORT THE
GRIEVING HERE IN SANDY HOOK.
PAYING TRIBUTE TO SHOW THEIR
SUPPORT FOR THIS HEARTBROKEN
COMMUNITY.
THERE'S A SIMPLE SPRAY-PAINTED
SIGN IN NEWTOWN UNDER AN
UNDERPASS.
"THERE IS NO FOOT SO TINY THAT
IT CAN'T LEAVE AN IMPRINT ON
THIS WORLD."
TODAY, 26 SETS OF FOOTPRINTS
LEAVING THEIR MARK.
FROM VIGILS ACROSS THE COUNTRY
TO A CHILDREN'S CHOIR ON
"SATURDAY NIGHT LIVE."
♪ SLEEP IN HEAVENLY PEACE
>> Reporter: AT THE NEW ENGLAND
PATRIOTS GAME.
26 FLARES BEFORE KICKOFF.
ONE FOR EACH LIFE TAKEN FAR TOO
SOON AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
BASKETBALL STARS SUCH AS LeBRON
JAMES AND CHRIS BOSH CLUTCHED
THEIR OWN SONS DURING A MOMENT
OF SILENCE IN MIAMI.
>> WE ASK THAT YOU NOW PLEASE
RISE, OUR THOUGHTS AND PRAYERS
GO OUT TO THE FAMILIES AFFECTED
BY THIS TRAGEDY.
>> Reporter: AND THEN, THERE WAS
NEW YORK GIANTS WIDE RECEIVER
VICTOR CRUZ.
>> IT WAS EMOTIONAL.
I WAS FIGHTING BACK TEARS A
LITTLE BIT.
>> Reporter: SCRAWLED ON HIS
CLEAT, A SPECIAL TRIBUTE TO JACK
PINTO.
ONE OF THE FIRST GRADERS KILLED
AND ONE OF CRUZ'S BIGGEST FANS.
CRUZ SO MOVED,
HE REACHED OUT TO THE PINTO
FAMILY WHO TOLD HIM THEY'RE
CONSIDERING BURYING JACK IN HIS
FAVORITE VICTOR CRUZ JERSEY.
>> I WAS HONORED.
I COULDN'T EXPRESS TO THEM HOW
GREAT THAT MADE ME FEEL.
I TOLD THEM TO STAY STRONG AND
I'LL DO WHATEVER I CAN TO HONOR
THEM.
>> Reporter: ONE OF THE MANY
HONORS THIS MORNING HELPING THE
PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN HEAL.
THEIR HEARTS BROKEN, BUT THEIR
SPIRITS STRONG.
♪ SLEEP IN HEAVENLY PEACE
>> AS PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID LAST
NIGHT, NEWTOWN IS NOT ALONE.
>>> TIME NOW TO RETURN TO TIMES
SQUARE FOR THE WEATHER AND SAM
CHAMPION.
>> OUR THOUGHTS ARE WITH
EVERYONE THERE.
WE'LL BEGIN WITH A GIANT PATTERN
CHANGE ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
WE HAVEN'T SEEN A LOT OF
WINTRY-LIKE WEATHER HERE.
NOW WE'LL BEGIN TO SEE A BIG
SHIFT IN THE JET STREAM.
SEVERAL STORMS FROM THE WEST
COAST ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
SNOW IN NORTHERN NEW ENGLAND
TODAY.
ALSO SOME RAIN.
ONE STORM SYSTEM REPLACES
ANOTHER ONE.
UP TO TWO INCHES OF RAIN ON THE
EASTERN SEABOARD.
A QUICK LOOK AT THE BIG BOARD
THERE.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT SEVERE WEATHER
IN THE NEXT HALF HOUR.
>>> AND AS WE CONTINUE OUR
COVERAGE FROM SANDY HOOK, YOU
HAVE A POWERFUL INTERVIEW WITH
TWO PARENTS WHO SAY TALKING
ABOUT THEIR CHILDREN BRINGS THEM
TINY MOMENTS OF COMFORT.
THAT'S AN ABC NEWS EXCLUSIVE.
>>> AND THE FIRST RESPONDERS IN
THEIR OWN WORDS.
WHAT THEY FOUND WHEN THEY
ARRIVED ON THE SCENE.
RESPONDERS IN
THEIR OWN WORDS.
WHAT THEY FOUND WHEN THEY
ARRIVED ON THE SCENE.
♪
THEY'RE WHOLE GRAIN GOOD...
AND YUMMY GOOD.
REAL FRUIT PIECES.
12 GRAMS OF WHOLE GRAINS
AND A CREAMY
YOGURT FLAVORED COATING.
QUAKER YOGURT GRANOLA BARS.
TREAT YOURSELF GOOD.
Whatever it takes, get toARS.
Sears Last Minute Gift Sale.
Don't judge me!
Get 50% off sleepwear for
her, and more with pass.
Save up to 70% off
all diamonds,
and up to 30% off all Small
Kitchen Appliances.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
♪
THE BLITZ.
THE DUNK.
NOTHING GOES BETTER
WITH FOOTBALL
THAN GOLDEN, CRISPY
Chicken McNuggets
FROM McDonald's,
DUNKED IN SPICY BUFFALO
AND CREAMY RANCH.
MORE GOOD TIMES TO LOVE.
♪
[Spider-Man]
WE GOT THIS.
♪
[Mom]
THIS HERO STUFF IS EASY!
>>> GOOD MORNING, I'M ERIC
THOMAS.
WE HAVE DEVELOPING NEWS IN SAN
FRANCISCO WHERE POLICE ARE
INVESTIGATING A HOME INVASION.
IT TOOK PLACE ON SLOAT BOULEVARD
RIGHT ACROSS FROM THE LAKESHORE
SHOPPING CENTER.
POLICE SAY THREE MEN WEARING
MASKS STORMED INTO THE HOME AND
TIED PEOPLE UP INSIDE.
INVESTIGATORS DON'T KNOW WHY
THAT HOME WAS TARGETED WHO ARE
OR WHAT WAS TAKEN.
NOBODY WAS HURT.
SUE HALL IS FOLLOWING THE
WEATHER MORNING COMMUTE.
>> WEATHER AND SLOW.
THIS IS 80 WESTBOUND AND FOGGY
AND MIST MISTY THERE.
WESTBOUND 80 AT GEORGIA, IN
VALLEJO.
STALL BLOCKING THE LEFT LANE AND
STILL IN NAPA.
HIGHWAY 121 SILVERADO TRAIL,
POWER LINES.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>>> WELCOME BACK, CHECK OUT
DOWNTOWN SAN FRANCISCO, LIGHT
RAIN AND IN FACT LET'S TAKE A
LOOK AT LIVE DOPPLER 7-HD.
RADAR RETURNS EVERYWHERE.
WHETHER IT'S DRIZZLE AND
EVERYBODY IS GETTING WET.
IT'S COMING FROM THE WEST AND
AROUND ABOUT NOON.
SCATTERED SHOWERS AND WATCH OUT
FOR
♪
>>> LOOKING AT JUST ONE OF THE
LIVING MEMORIALS THAT HAS SPRUNG
UP ALL OVER THIS SHATTERED TOWN.
TEDDY BEARS FOR THE LOST
CHILDREN AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
THE TOWN HAS COME TOGETHER
THROUGH THE WEEKEND AFTER THAT
SHATTERING LOSS ON FRIDAY.
WE'RE HERE AT THE NEWTOWN
METHODIST CHURCH.
I'M HERE WITH JOSH, AMY, AND
LARA.
WE'RE JOINED BY ELIZABETH IN NEW
YORK.
>>> THE FIRST RESPONDERS ARE
TRAINED TO BE HEROES.
THEY'RE SPEAKING OUT THIS
MORNING ABOUT WHAT THEY SAW ON
THE SCENE.
AND THEIR HEARTACHE AT NOT BEING
ABLE TO DO MORE EVEN AS THEY
SAVED CHILDREN'S LIVES.
>> AND THERE ARE SO MANY
QUESTIONS THIS MORNING ABOUT THE
SHOOTER, ADAM LANZA AND HIS
FAMILY.
WERE THERE WARNING SIGNS THAT
WERE MISSED WHEN IT CAME TO ADAM
LANZA?
COULD THIS VIOLENCE HAVE BEEN
PREVENTED?
WE'LL HAVE MUCH MORE ON THAT
DISCUSSION ABOUT MENTAL ILLNESS
IN A FEW MOMENTS.
BACK TO YOU IN NEWTOWN.
>>> THAT IS A CONVERSATIONS THAT
WILL CONTINUE ALL ACROSS THE
NATION.
THIS MORNING, 20 FAMILIES
DEALING WITH A LOSS THAT IS
IMPOSSIBLE TO IMAGINE.
THE LOSS OF A LITTLE CHILD.
YOU SPOKE TO ONE FAMILY WHO ALSO
INSPIRED YOU.
>> I HAVE NEVER BEEN SO MOVED OR
SO IMPACTED BY AN INTERVIEW AS I
WAS AFTER SITING DOWN WITH THE
REKOS FAMILY AND LISTENING TO
THEM REMEMBER THEIR LITTLE GIRL,
JESSICA WHO WAS SO VIOLENTLY
TAKEN AWAY THERE THEM.
SHE LOVED HORSES, ORCA WHALES
AND HER FAMILY.
HER PARENTS SAY FAULKING ABOUT
HER BRING TINY MOMENTS OF
COMFORT.
>> SHE WAS A BALL OF FIRE.
RULED THE ROOST.
>> OUR LITTLE CEO.
SHE WAS THE BOSS.
>> Reporter: WHEN THE CALL CAME
ON FRIDAY MORNING THAT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY WAS ON LOCKDOWN,
CHRISTA RUSHED THROUGH THE TOWN
WHERE SHE AND HER HUSBAND WERE
BOTH RAISED.
>> AS I WAS RUNNING, I KEPT
THINKING, I'M COMING FOR YOU,
HONEY, I'M COMING FOR YOU.
>> WE HAD NO IDEA.
WE THOUGHT, OKAY, THE REPORTS
THAT ONE OR TWO PEOPLE HAY HAVE
BEEN INJURED.
>> I WALKED AROUND THE FIRE
HOUSE, LIKE, MAYBE SHE'S IN
THERE.
>> I MUST HAVE DONE 100 LAPS.
>> I KNEW WHAT SHE WAS WEARING.
I THOUGHT I WOULD SEE THE PONY
TAIL, THE BLACK GLITTERY UGGS
SHE HAD ON THAT MORNING.
>> THERE WAS STILL HOPE THAT THE
CHILDREN WERE HIDING.
>> THEY FINALLY, AROUND 1:15
ASKED EVERYBODY TO SIT DOWN.
AND THEY SAID THAT, UM, IT WAS A
TRAGIC DAY IN NEWTOWN TODAY AND
20 CHILDREN WERE KILLED.
AND -- THEY TOLD ME MY LITTLE
GIRL WAS GONE.
>> THERE WAS SO MUCH PANIC AND
CONFUSION.
LIFE WAS SUCKED OUT OF EVERYONE
IN THE ROOM.
AND YOU KNOW, I -- JUST POINT
BLANK FOUND A STATE TROOPER AND
WAS LIKE, ARE THERE ANY
SURVIVORS.
ARE YOU TELLING ME THAT,
STANDING HERE AS A PARENT, MY
CHILD IS GONE?
HE SAID YES.
>> Reporter: OVERCOME WITH
GRIEF, THEY RETURNED HOME.
>> I GOT INTO HER BED THAT SHE
HAD JUST GOTTEN OUT OF.
AND, UM -- WE STAID IN BED.
STILL NOT REAL THAT MY -- MY
LITTLE GIRL, SO FULL OF LIFE AND
WHO WANTS A HORSE SO BADLY, AND
WHO IS GOING GET COWGIRL BOOTS
FOR CHRISTMAS ISN'T COMING HOME.
>> Reporter: THEY SAY THE PAIN
IS JUST SETTLING IN.
ARE YOU ANGRY?
>> THAT HASN'T REGISTERED TO ME.
THE KILLER'S FACE, THE NAME, I
JUST -- I SEE THROUGH IT RIGHT
NOW.
>> I JUST WANT TO KEEP TALKING
ABOUT HER AND -- ALL THE THINGS
SHE LOVED TO DO.
>> Reporter: SHE WAS THEIR
6-YEAR-OLD FAMILY POWERHOUSE,
FOREVER THEIR ANGEL.
>> I FOUND A LITTLE JOURNAL.
I DON'T KNOW WHEN IT'S FROM.
I HOEPD THE BOOK.
IT WAS EXACTLY WHAT I NEEDED
BECAUSE IT SAYS I LOVE YOU SO
MUCH, MAMA.
IT WAS LIKE SHE KNEW WE WERE
GOING NEED SOMETHING TO HELP US
GET THROUGH THIS.
THAT'S JUST LIKE WHAT AN AMAZING
LITTLE GIRL SHE WAS.
>> JESSICA WAS JUST 6 YEARS OLD.
HER FUNERAL IS TOMORROW.
I WANTED TO SHARE A STORY.
BEFORE THIS INTERVIEW BEGAN, WE
WERE LOOKING AT BABY PICTURES OF
HER WITH THE FAMILY.
I SAID, WHAT DAY WAS SHE BORN.
SAY SAID MAY 10, 2006.
THAT IS THE DAY I GAVE BIRTH TO
MY DAUGHTER.
AND I FELT SUCH A CONNECTION TO
CHRISTA, KNOWING SHE AND I GAVE
BIRTH ON THE SAME DAY AND
KNOWING HER DAUGHTER WAS NEVER
COMING HOME.
THE IMPACT WAS JUST, I FELT IT
RIGHT HERE.
>> YOU COULD SEE IT IN THEIR
FACE.
TO REMEMBER HER AND BE ABLE TO
SHARE HER STORY WITH THE
COUNTRY.
>> IT'S IMPORTANT TO THEM AND
ALL THE VICTIMS' FAMILIES THAT
THEIR STORIES ARE HEARD.
>> WE TURN TO THE FIRST
RESPONDERS.
THEY RECEIVED A STANDING OVATION
BEFORE LAST NIGHT'S VIGIL.
THE POLICE OFFICERS AND
FIREFIGHTERS WERE FIRST ON THE
SCENE, TRYING TO DO WHATEVER
THEY COULD TO GET THE PEOPLE TO
SAFETY.
WE TALKED TO THE FIRST
RESPONDERS IN AN ABC NEWS
EXCLUSIVE.
THEY ARE TRAINED TO BE HEROES.
ON FRIDAY MORNING, THE TEAM OF
FIRST RESPONDERS ARRIVED AT THE
SCENE WITHIN MINUTES.
PREPARED TO SAVE LIVES AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY.
>> WE SET UP A TRIAGE AREA RIGHT
BY THE RESCUE TRUCK.
>> Reporter: THEY WAITED,
HOPEFUL.
THEN THE HORROR BEGAN TO SET IN.
>> IT WAS ASTONISHING TO HEAR
WHAT WE WERE SUPPOSED TO BE
PREPARED FOR.
THERE WAS HOPE WE WOULD BE ABLE
TO HELP PEOPLE.
>> Reporter: AS THOSE MOMENTS
PASSED AND YOU REALIZED YOU WERE
NOT GOING TO BE CALLED UPON,
WHAT WAS THAT LIKE?
>> WE ARE TRAINED TO DO THIS.
WE WANTED TO HELP PEOPLE.
THERE WAS NOTHING WE COULD DO.
>> TWLERP THAT DAY TO DO
ANYTHING WE COULD FOR THEIR
CHILDREN.
WE'RE GOING TO DO WHATEVER WE
CAN FOR THEM.
>> WE WISH WE COULD HAVE DONE
MORE.
>> Reporter: SO MANY FAMILIES
WOULD HAVE DONE ANYTHING TO SEE
THOSE FACES AGAIN.
I HAVE SPOKE ON THE A LOT OF
PARENTS.
SPOKE ABOUT THE WORST MOMENTS
WERE WHEN THEY GOT HERE AND THEY
HOPED TO SEE THEIR CHILD.
>> IT WAS THE BIGGEST ROLLER
COASTER OF EMOTION TO SEE ONE
FAMILY REUNITE AND ANOTHER ONE
STILL LOST.
>> WE KNEW THAT POINT THERE
WAS -- THERE WASN'T GOING TO BE
GOOD NEWS.
>> Reporter: AS THE HOURS
PASSED, SO, TOO, DID THE HOPE.
BUT SOME PARENTS JUST COULDN'T
LEAVE THAT FIRE HOUSE.
HOW LONG DID THOSE PARENTS STAY?
>> SOME OF THEM QUITE AWHILE.
SOME OF THEM STAYED MOST OF THE
NIGHT THERE.
>> SOME OF THOSE GORGEOUS KIDS
AND THE BIG EYES.
IT'S SO SAD.
THEY'RE SO INNOCENT.
THEY DID NOTHING WRONG.
THEY DID NOTHING TO DESERVE
THIS.
>> Reporter: AND THEY HAVE TO
PUT SO MUCH ASIDE.
THE WOMAN YOU SAW THERE WORKED
THREE HOURS THE MORNING OF THE
SHOOTING, NOT KNOWING IF HER
MOTHER, AN EMPLOYEE AT THE
SCHOOL HIDING IN A CLOSET, WAS
SAFE.
SHE WAS, THOUGH.
>>> WE GO BACK TO TIMES SQUARE
AND SAM.
>> WE'RE GOING BEGIN WITH THE
THUNDERSTORMS IN THE DEEP SOUTH.
THIS WEEK, WE MAKE THE PATTERN
CHANGE.
THE JET STREAM BECOMES ACTIVE.
WE'LL FIND STORM SYSTEMS LIKE
THIS ONE.
LOUISVILLE, TALLAHASSEE.
ATLANTA.
COLUMBIA, SOUTH CAROLINA,
INVOLVED IN THIS.
STORMS FROM WASHINGTON, D.C. TO
MOBILE TODAY.
A QUICK LOOK AT THE NORTHEAST.
IT'S DAMP AND FOGGY.
ONE STORM SYSTEM IS REPLACED BY
>> ALL OF AMERICA'S WEATHER
RIGHT HERE ON "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA" IN THE NEXT HALF HOUR.
ELIZABETH?
>>> COMING UP, WHAT DID ADAM
LANZA'S MOTHER KNOW?
AND WERE THERE WARNING SIGNS
MISSED WHEN IT CAME TO THE
SHOOTER?
♪
[ engine revs ]
[ Male Announcer ]
OH WHAT FUN IT IS TO RIDE.
GET THE MERCEDES-BENZ
ON YOUR WISH LIST
AT THE WINTER EVENT GOING ON
NOW THROUGH DECEMBER 31ST.
[ Santa ] HO, HO, HO!
[ Male Announcer ] LEASE A 2013
E350 FOR $579 A MONTH
AT YOUR LOCAL
MERCEDES-BENZ DEALER.
FOR CENTURIES."
♪
THIS LEVIAN COLLECTION
IS AMAZING.
MAYBE IT'S TIME
TO START YOUR OWN.
[ Female Announcer ]
KAY JEWELERS PRESENTS
TODAY'S LEVIAN COLLECTION...
[ gasps ]
FEATURING EXCLUSIVE
LEVIAN CHOCOLATE DIAMONDS.
FROM THE LEVIAN FAMILY -
WHERE THE LATEST IN FASHION
MEETS FINE JEWELRY.
ONE MORE REASON KAY
IS THE NUMBER-ONE JEWELRY STORE
IN AMERICA.
IT'S...
A WORK OF ART?
♪ EVERY KISS BEGINS WITH KAY
FIVE DAYS LATER,
I HAD A MASSIVE HEART ATTACK.
BAYER ASPIRIN WAS THE FIRST
THING THE EMTS GAVE ME.
NOW, I'M ON
A BAYER ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Male Announcer ] BE SURE
TO TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE YOU BEGIN
AN ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Woman ]
LEARN FROM MY STORY.
>>> BACK NOW AT 7:41.
WE'RE STILL PIECING TOGETHER A
PICTURE OF THE SHOOTER, HIS HOME
LIFE, AND THE RELATIONSHIP HE
HAD WITH HIS MOTHER.
CAN YOU PREDICT SUCH VIOLENT
ACTIONS?
ARE THERE TELLTALE SIGNS?
FOLLOWING A WEEKEND OF
IMMEASURABLE GRIEF, SO MANY
QUESTIONS REMAIN.
WHY DID THIS HAPPEN?
COULD IT HAVE BEEN PREVENTED?
>> I'M SO SORRY.
>> Reporter: AT THE CENTER OF
THE MYSTERY, ADAM LANZA'S
MOTHER, NANCY.
SHE STRUGGLED WITH A SON WITH
INCREASING MOTION NAL ISSUES.
>> SHE SAID, IT'S GETTING
HARDER.
HE'S GETTING ORLANDO.
>> Reporter: ABC NEWS LEARNED
MOTHER AND SON SPENT TIME AT A
LOCAL GUN RANGE.
FRIENDS SAY NANCY WAS A SINGLE
MOTHER DOING THE BEST SHE COULD.
HAVE SHE CONSTANTLY TRIED TO
HELP HIM AND GET HELP FOR HIM.
SHE DID WHAT SHE COULD AS A
MOTHER.
>> Reporter: ON SATURDAY, THE
FAMILY'S FATHER RELEASED THIS.
OUR HEARTS ON GO OUT TO ALL HURT
AND INSXWRURPD WE, TOO, ARE
ASKING WHY.
HE JOINS A NUMBER OF OTHER
PARENTS WHO HAVE APOLOGIZED FOR
A CHILD'S VIOLENT ACT.
PEOPLE LIKE TAMMY ROBERTS, RO
WHO RAISED JAKE ROBERTS.
HE JUST WENT ON A SHOOTING SPREE
LAST WEEK.
>> NEVER COULD I IMAGINE HIM
BEING PART OF SUCH A THING LIKE
THIS.
AS HIS MOTHER, HE WILL ALWAYS BE
IN MY HEART.
>> Reporter: A SIMILAR MESSAGE
THAT THESE FRIENDS OF NANCY SAY
SHE WOULD HAVE GIVEN.
COULD THESE TRAGEDIES HAVE BEEN
SPRENT SND A QUESTION THAT THE
FAMILY, VICTIMS, AND THE NATION
ALIKE ARE WONDERING TODAY.
AND LET'S BRING IN PSYCHIATRIST
DR. JANET TAYLOR AND OUR LEGAL
ANALYST, DAN ABRAMS.
NANCY TOLD FRIENDS THAT SHE
THOUGHT HER SON SUFFERED FROM
ASPERGER'S.
HOW DO YOU PRECONVICT SOMEONE
COMMITTING A VIOLENT ACT?
>> THERE ARE FACTORS THAT HAVE
BEEN LINKED TO VIOLENCE.
ASPERGER'S DOESN'T NECESSARILY
MEAN THAT.
IF THERE'S UNDERLYING
DEPRESSION, MOOD DISORDER, OR
PARANOIA.
THOSE ARE SIGNIFICANT ASPECTS AS
WELL.
IF THERE'S BEEN A TRANSITION, A
LOSS OF A GIRLFRIEND, SOMETHING
LIKE THAT.
>> HE REPORTEDLY SUFFERED FROM A
CONDITION WHERE HE DID NOT FEEL
ANY PHYSICAL PAIN.
IS THAT AN IND CARROT OF
ANYTHING?
>> IT REALLY IS NOT.
THE QUESTION IS, HOW WOULD A
MOTHER HAVE KNOWN?
THERE'S NO WAY SHE COULD HAVE
KNOWN.
THERE'S NO WAY AS PROFESSIONALS
WE CAN PREDICT WHO WILL BE
VIOLENT AND COMMIT A MASS
MURDER?
1 IN EVERY 10 FAMILIES HAVE
ADOLESCENTS OR TEENS THAT HAVE
EMOTIONAL DISTURBANCES, AT HOME,
IN THE COMMUNITY, AT SCHOOL.
WE NEED TO ADDRESS THE
INDIVIDUALS, GET THEM INTO
TIMELY TREATMENT.
>> THERE ARE A LOT OF QUESTIONS
ABOUT WHY NANCY LANZA HAS FIVE
WEAPONS IN THE HOME, TOOK HER
SON TO A GUN RANGE WHERE HE
UNDOUBTEDLY LEARNED TO USE THEM.
WHEN HE WAS UNSTABLE.
HE WAS UNSTABLE ENOUGH THAT SHE
TOOK HIM OUT OF SCHOOL.
>> IF THE GUNS ARE LEGAL, YOU
WOULD HOPE THEY WOULD GO TO A
RANGE TO LEARN TO USE A WEAPON.
LET'S REMEMBER, SHE'S DEAD NOW.
SHE'S BEEN SHOT AND KILLED.
>> SHE, TOO, IS A VICTIM.
>> THERE'S NOT GOING TO BE LEGAL
LIABILITY TO HER.
VERY NAUFB THESE KINDS OF CASES,
WE SEE KIDS SHOOTING OTHER KIDS.
WE SAY, HOW MUCH RESPONSIBILITY
CAN THE PARENTS HAVE?
HERE, AN ADULT.
20 YEARS OLD.
NOT A CHILD.
THE MOTHER IS DEAD.
THERE ARE NOT GOING TO BE A TON
OF LEGAL QUESTIONS HERE.
CERTAINLY NOT CRIMINAL.
IT WILL BE TOUGH TO THINK ABOUT
CIVIL.
>> I THINK WE HAVE TO BE
CAREFUL.
A NUMBER OF PARENTS HOME
SCHOOL THEIR KIDS SUCCESSFULLY.
IF YOU HAVE A CHILD WITH A
MENTAL ILLNESS, THEY SHOULD NOT
BE AROUND GUNS OR FIRE ARMS AT
ALL.
>> PERIOD.
MUCH MORE TO COME.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
WELCOME HOME.
SHE LOVES IT.
NINTENDO 3DS XL!
NAILED IT.
DAD, I'M ACTUALLY
TOTALLY SATISFIED AND
HAVE NO COMPLAINTS.
HO, HO, HO!
SO SMART WITH YOUR MONEY!
PLUS FREE SHIPPING
AT TARGET.COM.
WITH YOUR RED CARD
GET AN EXTRA 5% OFF
OUR EVERYDAY LOW PRICES...
PLUS FREE SHIPPING.
SMOKE?
NAH, I'M GOOD.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERY TIME YOU SAY NO
TO A CIGARETTE,
YOU CELEBRATE A LITTLE WIN.
NICODERM CQ,
THE PATCH WITH TIME RELEASE
SMART CONTROL TECHNOLOGY
THAT ACTS FAST AND HELPS
CONTROL CRAVINGS ALL DAY LONG.
♪
QUIT ONE DAY AT A TIME
WITH NICODERM CQ.
GINGERBREAD COOKIE COFFEES --
NO WONDER PEOPLE GET JOLLY
AROUND THE HOLIDAYS.
TRY DUNKIN' DONUTS'
HOLIDAY FLAVORS.
PICK SOME UP WHERE YOU BUY
GROCERIES, BEFORE THEY'RE GONE.
AMERICA RUNS ON DUNKIN'.
AWW MAN.
[ Male Announcer ] RETURNS
ARE EASY WITH FREE PICKUP
FROM THE U.S. POSTAL SERVICE.
WE'LL EVEN DROP OFF BOXES
IF YOU NEED THEM.
VISIT USPS.COM
PAY, PRINT,
AND HAVE IT PICKED UP FOR FREE.
ANY TIME OF YEAR.
♪
NICE SWEATER.
THANK YOU.
♪
TO PRACTICE MATH
MORE?
I LOVE MATH!
BUT TWO iPADS
MEANS TWO DATA PLANS?
THAT'S CRAZY.
MAYBE NOT.
WITH AT&T MOBILE SHARE,
ADDING AN iPAD
IS JUST $10 A MONTH.
BUT HONESTLY, MOM AND DAD'S LOVE
IS ALL I REALLY NEED.
WE SHOULD KEEP THESE
FOR US.
WE SHOULD KEEP THESE.
WHAT?!
[ Male Announcer ]
AT&T MOBILE SHARE.
ADD AN iPAD
FOR JUST $10 A MONTH.
ONE PLAN. UP TO 10 DEVICES.
AT&T. RETHINK POSSIBLE.
PROGRESSIVE DIRECT AND OTHER
CAR INSURANCE COMPANIES?
YES.
BUT YOU'RE PROGRESSIVE,
AND THEY'RE THEM.
YES.
BUT THEY'RE HERE.
ARE YOU...?
THERE?
YES.
NO.
ARE YOU THEM?
I'M ME.
BUT THOSE RATES
ARE FOR...        THEM.
SO THEM ARE HERE.
YES!
YOU WANT TO RUN
THROUGH IT AGAIN?
NO, I'M GOOD.
YOU GOT IT?
YES.
RATES FOR US AND THEM --
NOW THAT'S PROGRESSIVE.
CALL OR CLICK TODAY.
>>> COMING UP ON "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA," YOUR CHILDREN, FEELING
SAFE AT SCHOOL, A NATIONAL
CONVERSATION.
For months, I had this deep pain
all over my body.
It just wouldn't go away.
My doctor diagnosed it
as fibromyalgia,
thought to be the
result of overactive nerves
that cause chronic
widespread pain.
Lyrica is believed
to calm these nerves.
I learned Lyrica can provide
significant relief
from fibromyalgia pain.
And for some people,
it can work in as early as
the first week of treatment.
So now I can plan my days
and accomplish more.
Lyrica is not for everyone.
Lyrica may cause serious
allergic reactions
or suicidal thoughts or actions.
Tell your doctor right away
if you have these,
new or worsening depression,
or unusual changes in mood
or behavior,
or any swelling or
affected breathing or skin,
or changes in eyesight,
including blurry vision
or muscle pain with fever
or tired feeling.
Common side effects
are dizziness, sleepiness,
weight gain, and swelling of
hands, legs and feet.
Don't drink alcohol
while taking Lyrica.
Don't drive or use machinery
until you know
how Lyrica affects you.
With less pain,
I'm feeling better
now that I've found Lyrica.
Ask your doctor
if Lyrica is right
for your fibromyalgia pain.
>>> GOOD MORNING, I'M ERIC
THOMAS.
CHURCH SERVICES AND VIGILS ARE
HELPING PEOPLE COPE WITH THE
SCHOOL TRAGEDY.
STILL DEVELOPING THIS MORNING AS
SERVICES ARE BEING HELD FOR TWO
OF THE YOUNG VICTIMS.
TONIGHT AT 7:00 THERE WILL BE A
SERVICE IN BURLINGAME.
IT TAKES PLACE AT FIRST
PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH.
WE'RE IN FOR WET WEATHER THIS
WEEK.
>> BY THE EVENING, ACTIVITIES,
THIS STEADY RAIN WILL BE OVER.
WE DO HAVE SCATTERED SHOWER
POSSIBLE DURING THE AFTERNOON
HOURS ESPECIALLY AFTERNOON WHEN
THE STEADY RAIN ENDS.
WE HAVE A LOT OF RAIN COMING
THURSDAY THROUGH THE WEEKEND.
>> STILL JAMMED MacARTHUR MAZE,
ACCIDENT LEFT LANE IN OAKLAND.
>> THE NEWS CONTINUES NOW WITH
"GOOD MORNING AMERICA."
>>> GOOD MORNING, AMERICA, FROM
NEWTOWN.
THE PRESIDENT'S DRAMATIC CALL
FOR CHANGE AFTER THE DEADLIEST
GRADE SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
HISTORY.
>> LET US FIND THE STRENGTH TO
CARRY ON AND MAKE OUR COUNTRY
WORTHY OF THEIR MEMORY.
>> THIS MORNING, INDELIBLE
IMAGES OF THE YOUNGEST VICTIMS.
>> READY, AND GO.
♪ COME NOW ALL YOU
>> I WANT EVERYBODY TO KNOW WHAT
A SPECIAL LITTLE GIRL SHE WAS.
>> AS NATION JOINS TOGETHER TO
PRAY AND PREVENT MORE KILLING.
WHAT WILL IT TAKE?
WHAT CAN WE DO?
AMERICA'S SEARCH FOR ANSWERS, AN
AMERICAN CONVERSATION STARTS
RIGHT NOW ON "GMA."
>>> SADNESS HANGING OVER SANDY
HOOK THIS MORNING.
SEE THE CHURCH HERE, THE
METHODIST CHURCH OF NEWTOWN.
ALL ACROSS OPPORTUNITOWN, LIVI L
MEMORIALS SPRINGING UP.
GOOD MORNING, AMERICA.
I'M HERE WITH JOSH, AMY, AND
LARA HERE IN SANDY HOOK.
ELIZABETH IN NEW YORK.
WE CAN FEEL THE ANGER AND FEAR
RIPPLING ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
THE PRESIDENT SAYING, AMERICA
HAS TO CHANGE, WE HAVE TO
CHANGE.
SO MANY PARENTS, TEACHERS,
CITIZENS ASKING, WHAT CAN BE
DONE?
WHAT CAN BE DONE TO STOP THIS
MINDLESS VIOLENCE WE HAVE SEEN
TOO MUCH OF IN AMERICA IN RECENT
YEARS?
WE'LL EXAMINE THOSE QUESTIONS
ALL WEEK LONG ALL ACROSS THE ABC
NEWS PROGRAMS.
AS WE SEARCH FOR SOLUTIONS.
>>> THIS MORNING, PARENTS
WONDERING, WHAT CAN WE DO TODAY?
ARE MY CHILDREN SAFE WHEN I SEND
THEM TO SCHOOL?
SECURITY BEEFED UP ACROSS THE
COUNTRY AS KIDS HEAD BACK TO
SCHOOL AT THIS MOMENT.
>>> AND WE'RE GOING CELEBRATE
THE HERO PRINCIPAL.
SHE PUT HER STUDENTS FIRST,
SACRIFICED HER OWN LIFE.
WE'LL HEAR FROM HER FAMILY IN AN
ABC NEWS EXCLUSIVE.
>> AS ALL THOSE CHILDREN AROUND
THE COUNTRY ARE GOING BACK THE
SCHOOL THIS MONDAY MORNING,
WE'RE GOING HAVE SOME YOUNG
CHILDREN HERE IN THE STUDIO IN A
TRIBUTE OF THEIR OWN TO THE
VICTIMS.
YOU SAW THE CHILDREN ON
"SATURDAY NIGHT LIVE" SINGING TO
OPEN THE SHOW ON SATURDAY.
THE FIRST TIME SINCE 9/11 THEY
HAVE OPENED A SHOW IN THIS
MANNER.
THIS MORNING, WE'RE GOING TO
HAVE THE YOUNG PEOPLE'S CHORUS
OF NEW YORK CITY LIFTING THEIR
VOICES TO HONOR THOSE WHO LOST
THEIR LIVES IN THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SHOOTINGS.
JOSH AND GEORGE?
>> WHAT A REMARKABLE MOMENT IT
WAS, ELIZABETH.
>>> WE BEGIN WITH PRESIDENT
OBAMA PS EMOTIONAL VISIT HERE
LAST NIGHT.
THE PRESIDENT MEETING WITH THE
FAMILIES DEVASTATED BY THE
TRAGEDY AND DELIVERING A
POWERFUL SPEECH AS HE PAID
TRIBUTE TO THE VICTIMS.
THE PRESIDENT WAS GREETED WITH A
STANDING OVATION AS HE ENTERED
THE HIGH SCHOOL AUDITORIUM,
FILLED WITH GRIEVING COMMUNITY
MEMBERS.
MANY OF THEM SURVIVING SANDY
HOOK SCHOOL CHILDREN, CLUTCHING
THEIR STUFFED ANIMALS.
>> ALL ACROSS THIS LAND OF OURS,
WE HAVE WEPT WITH YOU.
NEWTOWN, YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
>> Reporter: THE SERVICE GOT
UNDER WAY NEARLY AN HOUR LATE AS
THE PRESIDENT FIRST MET
PRIVATELY WITH FAMILY MEMBERS OF
THOSE KILLED, INCLUDING THE
INFANT GRANDDAUGHTER OF DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG.
>> WE SAY WE'RE TRULY DOING
ENOUGH TO GIVE ALL THE CHILDREN
OF THE COUNTRY THE CHANCE THEY
DESERVE TO LIVE OUT THEIR LIVES
IN HAPPINESS AND WITH PURPOSE.
WE'RE NOT DOING ENOUGH.
AND WE WILL HAVE TO CHANGE.
>> Reporter: AND THIS MORNING,
NEW DETAILS HAVE EMERGED ABOUT
THE GUNMAN, ADAM LANZA, WITH ONE
FORMER AQUAN TNS DESCRIBING HIM
AS A YOUNG MAN WHO KNEW KNOW
PAIN.
>> IF HE CUT HIMSELF OR HURT
HIMSELF, HE WOULD NOT KNOW IT OR
FEEL IT.
>> Reporter: NEW EVIDENCE
SUGGESTS THAT THE DEATH TOLL
COULD HAVE BEEN MUCH HIGHER HAD
AUTHORITIES NOT ARRIVED WHEN
THEY DID.
>> IS THE RESPONSE, THE ARRIVAL,
THE IMMEDIATE ENTERING OF THE
FACILITY, THAT SAVED A NUMBER OF
LIVES.
>> Reporter: THE PRESIDENT WAS
NOT SPECIFIC ABOUT WHAT HE'LL DO
TO PREVENT SIMILAR TRAGEDIES.
PLU PEOPLE PREDICT TIGHTENED GUN
CONTROL WILL BE A PRIORITY IN
HIS SECOND TERM.
>> IF THERE'S EVEN ONE STEP WE
CAN TAKE TO SAVE ANOTHER CHILD,
OR ANOTHER PARENT FROM THE GRIEF
THAT'S VISITED NEWTOWN, THEN
SURELY WE HAVE AN OBLIGATION TO
TRY.
>> A BRACING CALL TO ACTION FROM
PRESIDENT OBAMA RIGHT THERE.
WE WANT TO GO TO BRIAN ROSS,
BACK IN NEW YORK.
AS INVESTIGATORS STILL TRY TO
PIECE TOGETHER WHAT WAS DRIVING
THIS KILLER.
>> Reporter: POLICE ARE
EXAMINING COMPUTERS RECOVERED
FROM THE HOME OF ADAM LANZA AND
COMPUTERS TAKEN FROM FAMILY
MEMBERS.
THEY HAVE ESTABLISHED THAT T THE
YOUNG MAN, AFTER FIRST KILLING
HIS MOTHER WITH AN AWE SASSAULTE
RIFLE WENT TO SCHOOL WITH ENOUGH
BULLETS TO KILL EVERY SINGLE
PERSON AT THE SCHOOL, STUDENTS
AND STAFF.
FRIENDS OF THE FAMILY SAY ADAM
SUFFERED FROM SEVERAL DISORDERS,
WAS IN THE CARE OF A SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST.
IN THE LAST FEW MONTHS, HIS
MOTHER TOLD FRIENDS SHE WAS
LOSING CONTROL OF HIM, GEORGE?
>> OKAY, BRIAN, THANKS VERY
MUCH.
WE WANT TO GO BACK TO ELIZABETH
WITH THE NEWS IN NEW YORK.
>>> THANK YOU SO MUCH, GEORGE.
WEE GO PAULA FARIS WITH SOME
MORE GUN VIOLENCE IN THE
HEADLINES THIS MORNING.
>>> WE BEGIN WITH MORE GUN
VIOLENCE FAR WAY FROM
CONNECTICUT.
TWO POLICE OFFICERS SHOT AND
KILLED IN TOPEKA, KANSAS.
THE OFFICERS WERE RESPONDING TO
A REPORT OF A SUSPICIOUS VEHICLE
LAST NIGHT WHEN THEY WERE SHOT
IN THE HEAD.
IT'S BEEN MORE THAN A DECADE
SINCE A TOPEKA POLICE OFFICER
WAS KILLED IN THE LINE OF DUTY.
>>> IN WASHINGTON, REPORTS OF
PROGRESS TO AVOID THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
JOHN BOEHNER IS IN AGREEMENT
WITH TAX HIKES FOR PEOPLE MAKES
MORE THAN $1 MILLION A YEAR.
>>> HILLARY CLINTON IS AT HOME
RECOVERING FROM A CONCUSSION SHE
EXPERIENCED REPORTEDLY DUE TO
DEHYDRATION.
IT'S REPORTED THAT JOHN KERRY IS
SET TO REPLACE HER AS SECRETARY
OF STATE.
>>> THE PROBES WILL END A
YEAR-LONG MISSION BY
INTENTIONALLY CRASHING INTO THE
LUNAR SURFACE TODAY.
NEAR THE MOON'S NORTH POLE.
>>> AND FINALLY, YOU CAN EXPECT
LONG LINE AT THE POST OFFICE
TODAY.
THE BUSIEST MAILING DAY OF THE
YEAR.
BECAUSE MANY OF US SPENT THE
WEEK END ADDRESSING OUR
CHRISTMAS CARDS AND PACKAGES.
OVER 100 MILLION MORE PIECES OF
MAIL WILL BE PROCESSED TODAY.
THE BIGGEST DELIVERY DAY FOR
CARDS IS WEDNESDAY.
PACKAGES IS THURSDAY.
>>> NOW WITH THE WEATHER, HERE'S
SAM CHAMPION.
>> THE NEXT STORM INTO THE
NORTHWEST WITH POWERFUL WINDS.
WITH THAT, COLDER AIR AND
MOUNTAIN SNOW.
50-MILE-AN-HOUR WINDS AND SNOW
BLOWING.
AND 60 TO 80-MILE-PER-HOUR WINDS
IN THE AREA IN RED.
THE COASTAL RAIN, MOUNTAIN SNOW.
A LOT OF SNOW ANYWHERE FROM THE
CASCADES ALL THE WAY TO THE
HIGHER ELEVATIONS OF UTAH AS
WELL.
IT'S CALM AND QUIET HERE.
MEM
MEMPHIS, 62, HOUSTON, 74.
MIDLAND, ODESSA WITH NICE
NUMBERS AS WELL.
PHOENIX, PALM SPRINGS.
A QUICK LOOK AT THE BIG BOARD.
ON THE WEST COAST THE STORMS
ROLLING IN.
ON THE EAST COAST, A LINE OF
>> MORE OF AMERICA'S WEATHER
COMING UP ON "GMA" IN JUST A
MINUTE.
NOW PAULA, ELIZABETH?
>>> COMING UP, SANDY HOOK'S HERO
PRINCIPAL.
WE SPEAK WITH HER FAMILY IN AN
ABC NEWS EXCLUSIVE.
>>> AND THE NATIONAL
CONVERSATION STARTING RIGHT NOW
AS WE SEARCH FOR SOLUTIONS FOR
MAKING ALL OF OUR SCHOOLS A
LITTLE BIT SAFER.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS BOB,
A REGULAR GUY
WITH AN IRREGULAR HEARTBEAT.
THE USUAL, BOB?
NOT TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
BOB HAS AFIB:
ATRIAL FIBRILLATION NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
A CONDITION THAT PUTS HIM
AT GREATER RISK FOR A STROKE.
[ GPS ] TURN LEFT.
I DON'T THINK SO.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR YEARS, BOB TOOK WARFARIN,
AND MADE A MONTHLY TRIP TO THE
CLINIC TO GET HIS BLOOD TESTED.
BUT NOT ANYMORE.
BOB'S DOCTOR RECOMMENDED
A DIFFERENT OPTION:
ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
XARELTO® IS THE FIRST AND ONLY
ONCE-A-DAY PRESCRIPTION
BLOOD THINNER
FOR PATIENTS WITH AFIB
NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
THAT DOESN'T REQUIRE
ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING.
LIKE WARFARIN,
XARELTO® IS PROVEN EFFECTIVE
TO REDUCE THE RISK
OF AN AFIB-RELATED STROKE.
THERE IS LIMITED DATA
ON HOW THESE DRUGS COMPARE
WHEN WARFARIN IS WELL MANAGED.
NO ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING
MEANS BOB CAN SPEND HIS
EXTRA TIME HOWEVER HE LIKES.
NEW ZEALAND!
XARELTO®
IS JUST ONE PILL A DAY,
TAKEN WITH THE EVENING MEAL.
AND WITH
NO DIETARY RESTRICTIONS,
BOB CAN EAT THE HEALTHY FOODS
HE LIKES.
DO NOT STOP TAKING
XARELTO® RIVAROXABAN
WITHOUT TALKING TO THE DOCTOR
WHO PRESCRIBES IT FOR YOU.
STOPPING MAY INCREASE YOUR RISK
OF HAVING A STROKE.
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU DEVELOP ANY SIGNS
OR SYMPTOMS OF BLEEDING,
LIKE UNUSUAL BRUISING
OR TINGLING.
YOU MAY HAVE A HIGHER RISK
OF BLEEDING
IF YOU TAKE XARELTO®
WITH ASPIRIN PRODUCTS,
NSAIDS OR BLOOD THINNERS.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE TAKING XARELTO®
IF YOU CURRENTLY HAVE
ABNORMAL BLEEDING.
XARELTO® CAN CAUSE BLEEDING,
WHICH CAN BE SERIOUS,
AND RARELY MAY LEAD TO DEATH.
YOU ARE LIKELY TO BRUISE
MORE EASILY ON XARELTO®,
AND IT MAY TAKE LONGER
FOR BLEEDING TO STOP.
TELL YOUR DOCTORS
YOU ARE TAKING XARELTO®
BEFORE ANY PLANNED MEDICAL
OR DENTAL PROCEDURES.
BEFORE STARTING XARELTO®,
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ANY CONDITIONS,
SUCH AS KIDNEY, LIVER
OR BLEEDING PROBLEMS.
READY TO CHANGE YOUR ROUTINE?
ASK YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
FOR MORE INFORMATION
INCLUDING COST SUPPORT OPTIONS,
CALL 1-888-XARELTO
OR VISIT GOXARELTO.COM.
FOR MORE INFORMATION
INCLUDING COST SUPPORT OPTIONS,
Introducing NOOK HD -
the world's best 7" tablet made
for reading and entertainment.
Your favorite magazines and
catalogs look better than ever.
And with scrapbooking,
you can save the
things you love,
bring them all together,
And be inspired like
never before.
Scrapbooking. Create
yours with Nook HD -
and even bigger with HD+.
Find yours at Barnes & Noble.
THEY'RE WHOLE GRAIN GOOD...
AND YUMMY GOOD.
REAL FRUIT PIECES.
12 GRAMS OF WHOLE GRAINS
AND A CREAMY
YOGURT FLAVORED COATING.
QUAKER YOGURT GRANOLA BARS.
TREAT YOURSELF GOOD.
BODY WASHES WITH PAPER
THAT REACTS LIKE SKIN.
IF OTHERS CAN STRIP THIS PAPER,
IMAGINE HOW HARSH
THEY CAN BE TO YOUR SKIN.
OH MY GOSH.
[ Female Announcer ]
Dove IS DIFFERENT.
ITS NEW BREAKTHROUGH FORMULA
CHANGES EVERYTHING.
NEW Dove.
THIS IS CARE.
TOMATO,
OBVIOUSLY.
HAHA. THERE'S MORE
THAN THAT THOUGH,
THERE'S A KICK TO IT.
WAHLALALALALLALA!
SMOOTH, BUT CRISP.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE DRINKING
A FOOD THAT'S A DRINK,
OR A DRINK THAT'S A FOOD,
WOOOOOH!
[ Male Announcer ] TASTE IT
AND DESCRIBE THE INDESCRIBABLE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
[ Male Announcer ]
WATCH OUT, CASANOVA.
THERE'S A NEW LADIES' MAN
IN TOWN,
AND HE KNOWS TO SHOP AT
Walgreens DURING THE HOLIDAYS.
WE HAVE GREAT GIFTS
AT GREAT PRICES,
ONLINE AND IN THE STORE.
SO YOU'RE SURE TO FIND
SOMETHING
FOR THAT SPECIAL SOMEONE --
EVEN IF YOU HAVE
SEVERAL SPECIAL SOMEONES.
SHOP Walgreens FOR GREAT GIFTS,
LIKE Lindt Lindor Truffles,
AND MOST STORES ARE EVEN OPEN
TILL MIDNIGHT, HERE.
AT THE Corner
of Happy and Healthy.
>>> ONE OF THE LIVING MEMORIALS
HERE AT SANDY HOOK.
THERE ARE SO MANY HEROES COMING
OUT OF THIS TRAGEDY, ONE OF
THEM, THE SCHOOL'S PRINCIPAL,
WHO SACRIFICED HER LIFE TRYING
TO STOP THE SHOOTER.
AMY, YOU HAVE MORE ON A
REMARKABLE WOMAN.
>> I DO, INDEED.
PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG WAS
THE FEARLESS LEADER OF SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
HER FAMILY SAYING SHE FOUGHT FOR
HER STUDENTS EVERY DAY.
LAST FRIDAY WAS NO DIFFERENT.
THIS MORNING, DAWN HOCHSPRUNG IS
BEING REMEMBERED A HERO.
DAWN'S DAUGHTER TWEETED THIS
PHOTO SAYING MY MOM WOULD BE SO
PROUD TO SEE PRESIDENT OBAMA
HOLDING HER GRANDDAUGHTER.
BUT NOT AS PROUD AS I AM OF HER.
HOCHSPRUNG THREW HERSELF IN
FRONT OF ADAM LANZA.
>> THE PRINCIPAL OF THE SCHOOL
WAS RUNNING TOWARD THE SHOOTER
IN ORDER TO PROTECT HER
STUDENTS.
>> Reporter: AN AWARD-WINNING
PRINCIPAL IS BELIEVED TO HAVE
SAVED COUNTLESS LIVES BY TURNING
ON THE P.A. SYSTEM TO WARN
OTHERS.
>> I THOUGHT SHE WAS SCREAMING.
THAT'S WHAT WE HEARD OVER THE
LOUDSPEAKER.
WE HEARD KIDS CRYING.
>> WE HEARD THE LOUDSPEAKER AND
GUNS AND WE ALSO HEARD SCREAMING
AND CRYING.
>> Reporter: THE 47-YEAR-OLD
MOTHER AND GRANDMOTHER BECAME
PRINCIPAL TWOO YEARS AGO.
SHE MADE INCREASING SCHOOL
SECURITY A PRIORITY, ALL WHILE
KEEPING HER SENSE OF HUMOR BY
TRANSFOERMING HERSELF INTO THE
SANDY HOOK BOOK FAIRY TO
ENCOURAGE READING.
>> THIS WOMAN WAS THE LIFE OF
THE ENTIRE SCHOOL.
SHE WAS THE ROCK.
>> AND JOINING US NOW, DAWN'S
SON-IN-LAW, RYAN, AND HER CLOSE
FRIEND AND COUSIN, MELANIE.
FIRST OF ALL, WE'RE SO SORRY FOR
YOUR LOSS.
>> THANK YOU.
>> AND RYAN, THOUGH IT MUST BE
SOME COMFORT KNOW YOUR
MOTHER-IN-LAW DIED A HERO.
>> YES, THAT WAS THE -- THE ONLY
THING THATKY -- I DON'T WANT TO
HAVE A CONVERSATION LIKE THAT
WITH MY KIDS.
BUT, YOU KNOW, BEING ABLE TO
TELL THEM THAT YOU KNOW, SHE --
SHE SAVED A LOT OF CHILDREN AND,
YOU KNOW, WAS ABLE TO WARN
EVERYONE AND SHE SAVED A LOT OF
LIVES.
SO SHE'S A HERO.
>> YOU HAD THAT CONVERSATION
LAST NIGHT WITH THE PRESIDENT.
WE SAW THE PRESIDENT HOLDING
YOUR DAUGHTER, 6-MONTH-OLD
ALISON.
WHAT DID HE SAY TO YOU?
>> I WASN'T THERE.
MY WIFE ATTENDED.
I WAS HOME WITH THE REST OF
THEM.
>> WHAT CAN YOU TELL US?
>> HE SPENT TIME WITH THE
FAMILIES.
IT WAS NICE TO HAVE SOME KIND
WORDS FROM HIM.
>> AND MELANIE, WE SEE THE
STORIES OF DAWN AND SEE HOW
COMMITTED SHE WAS.
EXACTLY WHAT ANY PARENT WOULD
WANT IN A SCHOOL PRINCIPAL.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
I WOULD SAY ANYONE WHO WAS
PLANNING ON BEING A TEEMP, READ
THE LIFE OF DAWN HOCHSPRUNG.
BECAUSE SHE WAS THE IDEAL, THE
EPITOME OF WHAT TEACHING IS AND
WHAT A TEACHER IS SPOEUPPOSED T
BE.
SHE LOVED HER STUDENTS SO MUCH.
OBVIOUSLY, ENOUGH TO DIE FOR
THEM.
>> AND THE EMPITOME OF WHAT YOU
WOULD WANT IN A FRIEND?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
SHE WAS MY COUSIN.
BUT MORE LIKE A SISTER TO ME.
WE GREW UP TOGETHER.
WE WOULDN'T LET TWO OR THREE
DAYS GO BY WITHOUT TEXTING OR
CHATTING ON THE PHONE.
THERE'S A HOLE IN MY HEART.
I'M NOT SURE HOW THAT WILL BE
FILLED, IF IT EVER WILL WILL.
>> HOW ABOUT AS A MOTHER-IN-LAW?
YOU'RE LAUGHING.
>> SHE'S REALLY GREAT PERSON.
SHE WAS JUST -- SHE TREATED MY
KIDS LIKE GOLD.
I'M SURE SHE TREATED ALL OF HER
STUDENTS THAT WAY.
SHE'S JUST A JOY.
I WAS TALKING TO MELANIE ABOUT
IT.
I HAD TAKEN MY KIDS ON THE HIKE
ONE DAY.
IN A SMALL MOUNTAIN WITH A NICE
VIEW.
WE WERE SITTING AND EATING,
ANOTHER LADY CAME BY, SHE HAD A
T-SHIRT ON THAT WAS ONE OF HER
OLD SCHOOLS.
WE GOT THE TALKING.
SHE WAS LIKE, DAWN, WE WERE JUST
CHATTING.
SHE'S SO NICE.
AND -- I'M IN THE MIDDLE OF THE
WOODS, I THOUGHT ABOUT THAT IN
THE LAST FEW DAYS.
I'M IN THE MIDDLE OF THE WOODS.
>> FINALLY, BEFORE WITH E E GO,
IS THE ONE THING YOU WANT ALL OF
AMERICA TO KNOW ABOUT YOUR KUNZ
AND FRIEND?
>> THERE'S NOT JUST ONE THING.
SHE WAS SO VIBRANT, SO FULL OF
LIFE.
AND I WANT PEOPLE TO KNOW SHE
WAS A HERO.
WHEN I LEARNED THAT SHE ACTUALLY
TRIED TO TAKE THE GUNMAN DOWN,
IT WAS NO SURPRISE TO ME AT ALL.
MY ONLY HOPE IS THAT THE GUNMAN
ACTUALLY HAD A LITTLE BIT OF
FEAR, KNOWING THIS 5'2" RAGING
BULL WAS COMING AT HIM AND HE
HAD A LITTLE BIT OF FEAR IN HIS
EYES KNOWING SOMEONE LIKE DAWN
WAS COMING AFTER HIM BECAUSE HE
WAS TRYING TO HURT HER STUDENTS.
>> I'LL BET HE DID.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
>> LARA?
>>> WE REMEMBER DAWN THE HERO
PRINCIPAL.
CHILDREN HEAD BACK TO SCHOOL FOR
THE FIRST TIME THIS MORNING
SINCE FRIDAY'S SHOOTINGS.
YOUR CHILD MIGHT BE NERVOUS.
IT'S A DAUNTING BUT CRUCIAL
CHALLENGE FOR ALL OF US, HELPING
OUR KIDS FEEL SAFE IN THE
CLASSROOM.
>> THERE ARE MULTIPLE FATALITIES
INCLUDING CHILDREN.
>> Reporter: ACROSS THE COUNTRY,
CHILDREN GETTING SET TO GO BACK
TO SCHOOL.
>> IT'S IMPORTANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE
THEIR FEARS.
>> Reporter: TEEMPS LIKE LAUREN
GRAPPLE WITH NOW MAKE HER
CLASSROOM SAFE.
>>LY CONTINUE DO WHAT I CAN TO
ASSURE THEIR SAFETY.
>> THEY'LL BE REACHING OUT TO ME
FOR ANSWERS.
AS ADULTS, DWOENT HAVE THOSE
ANSWERS.
>> Reporter: ONE TEACHER'S
HOMEWORK WAS SIMPLE.
GO HOME AND HUG YOUR LOVED ONES.
ANOTHER TEACHER WROTE, I'LL BE
LOCKING MY DOOR THIS WEEK.
>> I'M WORRIED ABOUT HOW I'M
GOING THE FEEL AND LET GO OF HER
HANDS AS SHE GETS ON THE BUS.
>> Reporter: THIS MORNING,
SCHOOL DROPOFFS ARE A DIFFICULT
AND NECESSARY START TO A NEW
DAY.
>> ONE OF THE WAYS OF
DEMONSTRATING THAT THEIR LIVES
ARE SECURE AND RELIABLE IS TO
HAVE THEM DISRUPTED AS LITTLE AS
POSSIBLE.
>> Reporter: CHILD TRAUMA EXPERT
DR. STEVEN MARIN SAYS IT'S
IMPORTANT NOT TO AVOID
DISCUSSING FRIDAY'S EVENTS.
>> EVERYBODY HAS BEING FEELINGS
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED.
THE OPPORTUNITY HERE IS TO
PROVIDE A FORUM IN WHICH KIDS
CAN PUT INTO WORDS WHAT THEY'RE
THINKING ABOUT.
>> Reporter: NOW, AS THE NATION
MOURNS WITH CONNECTICUT, IT
STANDS, TOO, WITH SURVIVING
SCHOOLS AND THE PEOPLE WHO FILL
THEM WITH HOPE.
>> AND WE NOW ARE BEGINNING OUR
CONVERSATION WHAT ABOUT TO SAY
TO OUR KIDS ACROSS THE COUNTRY
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
JOINING US TO TALK ABOUT HOW
TEACHERS AND PARENTS WICAN HELD
THEIR CHILDREN FEEL SAVER,
JEFFREY, AND WILLOW BAY.
I WOULD LIKE TO START WITH YOU,
JEFFREY, THAEND HAVE WILLAND TH
WEIGH IN.
IT VARIES ON THE AGE OF THE
CHILD.
FOR CHILDREN 7 AND UNDER, WE
SHOULDN'T BE BRINGING THIS UP?
>> OUR YOUNG PEOPLE ARE NOT
CONSUMING HUGE AMOUNTS OF TV AND
RADIO THAT YOUNG AGE.
WE NEED TO MAKE SURE THEIR WORLD
GETS RIGHTED, THEIR ROUTINES GET
RE-ESTABLISHED.
MOSTLY TAKE THE TEMPERATURE OF
YOUNG KIDS, SEE IF YOU SEE
SCIENCE OF SADNESS OR ANXIETY.
YOU COULD ASK KIDS, ANYONE
CONCERNED NEED TO TALK ABOUT.
I WOULD NOT TRY TO GET VERY
YOUNG KIDS TO CONSUME THE STORY.
>> IF THEY DON'T ASK, DON'T
BRING IT UP?
>> LET THEM CONTINUE IN THE
WORLD THAT 5 AND 6-YEAR-OLDS
NEED TO LIVE IN WHERE THEY'RE
SAFE UNDER THE CARING WATCHFUL
EYE OF ADULTS.
THAT DOES NOT ASSUME THAT SOME
KIDS MAY HAVE HEARD SOMETHING
AND WE HAVE TO FIGURE OUT WHICH
KIDS WE NEED TO TALK TO.
>> IT'S IMPORTANT FOR PARENTS TO
BE CALM AND TO REASSURE THEM
THAT THEY ARE SAFE AND THERE ARE
GROWN-UPS TRYING TO KEEP THEM
SAFE?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
IT'S IMPORTANT FOR US AS PARENTS
TO MANAGE THE COMPLICATED AND
POWERFUL EMOTIONS WE HAVE OFF
CAMERA, IF YOU WILL.
TALK WITH OTHER ADULTS, WORK
WITH THEM ON OUR OWN, SHARE THEM
WITH YOUR CHILDREN IN A
CONTROLLED WAY AND IN A VERY
COMFORTABLE TONE TO ACKNOWLEDGE
THAT, YES THERE ARE VERY
POWERFUL FEELINGS.
THEN TO REASSURE CHILDREN, ALSO
IN VERY SPECIFIC AND CONCRETE
WAYS THAT THEIR SCHOOL IS SAFE.
GIVE THEM ACTUAL EXAMPLES,
BECAUSE LITTLE KIDS THINK VERY
CONCRETELY.
HERE ARE THE WAYS THAT ADULTS
ARE WORKING TO KEEP YOU SAFE.
YOUR TEEMP, YOUR PRINCIPAL.
MOM AND DAD.
HERE ARE SOME OF THE DRILLS THAT
YOU PRACTICE AT SCHOOL TO KEEP
YOU SAFE.
AGAIN, THOSE SPECIFICS GIVE THEM
COMFORT.
>> WHAT DO YOU DO WITH THE OLDER
KIDS WHO KNOW ENOUGH TO SAY, BUT
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY, THERE
WERE PRINCIPALS, GROWNUPS, A
SECURITY SYSTEM AND IT DIDN'T
WORK?
>> YOU ANSWER THEM VERY DIRECTLY
AND SIMPLY AND YOU RESPOND AND
TEEMPS KNOW THIS VERY WELL.
YOU RESPOND TO THE CUES OF YOUR
CHILD.
YOU WATCH YOUR CHILD VERY
CAREFULLY AS YOU'RE GIVING THEM
INFORMATION FOR CSIGNALS THAT
YOU'RE GIVING THEM ENOUGH AND
YOU ENCOURAGE THEM TO GIVE YOU
SIGNS TO GIVE THEM MORE DETAILS.
SIMPLE, FACTUAL, DIRECT.
LAYER ON THE DETAILS AS YOU
TALK.
>> GEOFFREY, YOU POINT OUT THAT
TEEMPS NEED TO BE ON THE LOOKOUT
FOR SIGNS OF ANXIETY IN THE
CLASSROOM BECAUSE OFTEN TIMES,
CHILDREN DON'T RAISE THEIR HANDS
AND SAY, I'M UPSET.
BUT THEY'LL ACT IT OUT.
>> HERE, WE HAVE AN IMPORTANT
ISSUE.
SOME YOUNG PEOPLE ARE VERY THEIR
OWN TRAUMA IN THEIR LIFE THAT
THIS ADDED ADDITIONAL TRAUMA IS
GOING TO REALLY TIP THEM REALLY
OVER AN EMOTIONAL EDGE.
WE NEED TO BE ABLE TO PROVIDE
SUPPORT FOR THOSE KIDS.
TEEM
TEACHERS NEED TO BE ABLE TO DO
TRIAGE.
SOME KIDS NEED AN ARM AROUND
THEM AND SAY, IT'S ALL RIGHT.
TIL TELL YOU THIS.
ALL OVER AMERICA, TEACHERS
SHOULD BE EXPLAINING TO CHILDREN
WHY IT'S IMPORTANT TO LISTEN BE
CALM, AND DO WHAT THEY'RE TOLD
WHEN AN EMERGENCY HAPPENS.
IT WILL MAKE KIDS FEEL BETTER
KNOWING THERE'S A PLAN.
>> AND YOU SAID ALSO, TEACHERS
MAY BE FEELING TRAUMA.
THERE WERE TEACHERS SLAIN IN
THIS AS WELL.
>> IN MY SCHOOLS, ALL OF MY
TEACHERS WORRY ABOUT THEIR
STUDENTS.
BUT THEY REALIZE FOR THE FIRST
TIME, AMERICAN TEACHERS ARE ON
THE FRONT LINES.
MOST OF THEM ARE NOT PREPARED
FOR THIS LEVEL OF FEAR.
>> SHOULD A PARENT TALK TO THEIR
CHILD ABOUT THE EVENT OF A
TERRIBLE PERSON COMING INTO
THEIR ZONE OF SAFETY?
>> THINK KIDS SHOULD HAVE A PLAN
AND PARENTS SHOULD REHEARSE PLAN
FOR THEM.
IT WILL GIVE EVERYBODY A MEASURE
OF COMFORT.
KNOWING THEY CAN DO SOMETHING.
>> WILLOW BAY, GEOFFREY CANADA.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
THE CONVERSATION WILL CONTINUE.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
>>> GOOD MORNING, I'M KRISTEN
SZE.
SAN FRANCISCO FIREFIGHTERS HAVE
RESCUED A MAN THAT GOT STUCK IN
A CHIMNEY OVERNIGHT.
IT HAPPENED AT MIDNIGHT ON CLAY
STREET AND PRESIDIO AVENUES.
THE RESCUE CAUSED A BIG
COMMOTION AS CREWS HAD TO LOOSEN
BRICKS TO GET HIM OUT.
THEY DON'T KNOW WHY HE WAS IN
THE CHIMNEY.
THE MAN IS EXPECTED TO BE OKAY.
YOUR MORNING COMMUTE, SLOW IN A
LOT OF PLACES.
>> STILL SLOW GETTING TO THE BAY
BRIDGE TOLL PLAZA, BACKED UP
ACROSS THE MacARTHUR MAZE.
YOU MIGHT WANT TO CONSIDER BART.
HIGHWAY 35 AND HIGHWAY 1 NEW
ACCIDENT.
NORTH 280 AT 380 A NEW ACCIDENT
REPORTED THERE, AS WELL.
>> METEOROLOGIST MIKE NICCO IS
TRACKING THE RAIN AND NOW
>>> WE HAVE PRETTY GOOD RADAR
RETURNS HEADING OVER TO HAYWARD
AND FROM SAN MATEO BACK TO MOSS
BEACH AND HALF MOON BAY.
A LITTLE MORE AROUND ALIM ROCK
AND FREMONT.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE WAVES OF
LIGHT RAIN TILL AT LEAST NOON
AND THEN SCATTERED SHOWERS AND
TEMPERATURES HOLDING RIGHT NOW
IN THE LOW TO MID-50s.
GET READY FOR
♪ SOMEWHERE OVER THE RAINBOW WAY
UP HIGH ♪
♪ THERE'S A LAND THAT I HEARD OF
ONCE IN A LULLABY ♪
>>> THE YOUNG PEOPLE'S CHORUS OF
NEW YORK CITY, LIFTING THEIR
VOICES TO HONOR AND REMEMBER AND
CELEBRATE THE LIVES LOST HERE IN
SANDY HOOK OVER THE WEEKEND.
WE'LL HEAR A LOT MORE FROM THEM
THIS HALF HOUR.
AS WE SAY GOOD MORNING FROM
SANDY HOOK.
I'M HERE WITH JOSH, AMY, AND
LARA.
AND ELIZABETH IN NEW YORK.
THIS COMMUNITY STRUGGLING SO
MUCH.
BUT A BIG MESSAGE THEY GOT LAST
NIGHT.
THE PRESIDENT TOLD THEM ALL HERE
THEY ARE NOT ALONE.
ALL OF AMERICA HERE AS WELL.
>> YOU CAN SEE THE MESSAGES ALL
OVER TOWN.
WE'VE ALL BEEN TAKING PICTURES.
THEY'RE SO HEARTFELT.
THE MESSAGES, THE FLOWERS, THE
TEDDY BEARS.
IT'S SUCH A TOUCHING TRIBUTE AS
PEOPLE TRY TO DO THE BEST THEY
CAN TO BEGIN TO PICK UP THE
PIECES.
>> WE'RE GOING TO NOW CONTINUE
A NATIONAL CONVERSATION.
BIG QUESTIONS THIS MORNING,
ABOUT GUNS, ABOUT MENTAL
ILLNESS, AND SCHOOL SAFETY.
TO THAT END, AS NATIONAL
CONVERSATION CONTINUES, WE'LL BE
EXPLORING THESE ISSUES ALL WEEK
LONG ACROSS ALL ABC NEWS
PLATFORMS.
ELIZABETH?
>> ALL RIGHT, JOSH.
>>> WE'RE ALSO GOING TO TALK TO
RELIGIOUS LEADERS IN NEWTOWN AND
ACROSS THE COUNTRY WHO ARE
TRYING TO START THE PROCESS OF
HEALING IN THIS SHATTERED
COMMUNITY.
THE RELIGIOUS LEADERS WILL BE
CRUCIAL TO THE HEARING PROCESS.
LARA?
>> THANK YOU, ELIZABETH.
>>> AS WE HAVE BEEN HERE ALL
WEEKEND LONG IN NEWTOWN, WE HAVE
BEEN JUST ASTOUND BID THE
ENORMOUS OUTPOURING OF SPOUPPOR
FROM THE PEOPLE ALL OVER THE
COUNTRY.
AS THE RESIDENTS OF NEWTOWN, THE
VICTIM, THE FAMILIES, START THE
PROCESS OF REBUILDING.
JUST THREE DAYS AFTER THE
UNTHINKABLE OCCURRED IN THIS
PICTURESQUE NEW ENGLAND TOWN,
NEWTOWN HAS BEEN TAKEN OVER BY
NEIGHBORS, FAMILY, AND STRANGERS
WHO CARE.
ALL WITH A SIMPLE MESSAGE.
THE VICTIMS WILL NOT BE
FORGOTTEN.
WHY WAS IT IMPORTANT TO BE OUT
TONIGHT?
>> WE HAVE TO TEACH OUR CHILDREN
HOW TO LOVE EACH OTHER.
>> Reporter: AT AN INTERFAITH
VIGIL LAST NIGHT, FAMILIES STOOD
FOR HOURS IN THE COLD RAIN FOR A
CHANCE TO COME TOGETHER AND
LISTEN TO WORDS OF COMFORT FROM
PRESIDENT OBAMA.
>> IN THE FACE OF UNCONSCIONABLE
EVIL, YOU HAVE LOOKED OUT FOR
EACH OTHER.
YOU HAVE CARED FOR ONE ANOTHER.
AND YOU HAVE LOVED ONE ANOTHER.
>> Reporter: AS THE NIGHTS WEAR
ON, MORE SIGNS OF HOPE.
THE WORDS, A POIGNANT REMINDER
OF WHAT MUST BE OVERCOME.
>> WE'RE ALL IN IT TOGETHER.
THAT BOY COULD HAVE BEEN MY SON.
WE HAVE TO EMBRACE THAT AND PRAY
FOR HIM AS WELL.
>> Reporter: AS STRANGERS BECOME
FAMILY, RANDOM ACTS OF KINDNESS
ARE EVERYWHERE.
>> THIS IS SUCH A SMALL TOWN.
FACE FROM FACES, WE KNOW EACH
OTHER.
WE SEE EACH OTHER AT THE DELI,
WE SEE EACH OTHER EVERYWHERE.
IT'S ONE FAMILY.
IT'S AFFECTED US ALL.
>> Reporter: LIKE A FAMILY, THE
PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN, WHETHER BORN
HERE OR BROUGHT HERE BY TRAGEDY
WILL FACE THE DIFFICULT DAYS
AHEAD BY RELYING ON EACH OTHER.
WORDS OF COMFORT AND SO MUCH
LOVE.
JOSH?
>> LARA, THIS HORRIFYING ATTACK
HAS REIGNITED A DEBATE OVER GUN
CONTROL.
BIG QUESTIONS ABOUT WHETHER
STRICTER LAWS CAN STOP MORE MASS
SHOOTINGS.
PIERRE THOMAS JOINS US WITH MORE
ON OUR NATION'S RELATIONSHIP
WITH GUNS.
PIERRE?
>> Reporter: JOSH, AS WE ATTEMPT
TO DEAL WITH THIS TRAGIC EVENT,
WE FOUND SOME EYE-POPPING
NUMBERS THAT SHOW SOLVING THIS
PROBLEM WILL BE COMPLICATED.
THE STATISTICS ARE STAGGERING.
ON BLACK FRIDAY, U.S. SHOPPERS
WERE NOT JUST BUYING TOYS AND
ELECTRONI
ELECTRONICS.
THEY WERE ALSO BUYING GUNS.
IN RECORD NUMBERS.
ON THAT SINGLE DAY, THE FBI DID
COMPUTERIZED BACKGROUND CHECKS
ON MORE THAN 154,000 PURCHASES
OF FIREARMS.
IN NOVEMBER ALONE, AMERICANS
TRIED TO BUY A WHOPPING 2
MILLION GUNS.
HERE ARE SOME FACTS THAT MIGHT
SURPRISE YOU.
THERE ARE MORE REGISTERED GUN
DEALERS AND STORES THAN MAJOR
SUPERMARKETS.
MORE GUN SELLERS THAN McDONALD'S
RESTAURANTS.
THE OVERWHELMING MAJORITY OF GUN
USERS ARE LAW-ABIDING CITIZENS.
THE MILLIONS OF GUNS ALREADY IN
CIRCULATION GUARANTEE THAT
DISTURBED PEOPLE WILL OFTEN BE
ABLE TO OBTAIN THEM, EVEN IN
QUIET COMMUNITIES LIKE NEWTOWN.
WE SPOKE TO THE FBI ON-SCENE
COMMANDER.
>> THERE ARE ABOUT 400 GUN
DEALERS IN A FOUR-COUNTY AREA.
WITHIN TEN MILES OF THE
INCIDENT, 36 GUN DEALERS.
>> Reporter: POLICE BELIEVE THE
GUNS ADAM LANZA USED WERE BOUGHT
LEGALLY.
>> IN AMERICA, UNLESS YOU HAVE A
FELONY CONVICTION OR YOU'RE
A JUDE KATED BY THE COURT TO BE
MENTALLY INCOMPETENT, YOU HAVE
THE RIGHT TO BEAR FIREARMS.
>> Reporter: THIS MORNING,
AMERICA IS LEFT WITH A QUESTION.
HOW DO YOU KEEP WEAPONS FROM MEN
LIKE THESE, WHEN THERE ARE AN
ESTIMATED 2 MILLION-PLUS GUNS
ALREADY IN CIRCULATION.
NO EASY ANSWERS, JOSH.
NO EASY ANSWERS.
>> TO MAKE THE POINT, THEN, IF
WE STOPPED GUN PRODUCTION IN THE
COUNTRY TODAY, WE COULD STILL BE
YEARS AND YEARS AWAY FROM A
SOLUTION ON THAT TASK.
>> GUNS ARE NOT BIO DEGRADABLE.
THEY'RE NOT GOING AWAY.
THE COUNTRY HAS TO FIGURE OUT
HOW TO DEAL WITH THE MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES AND THE GUNS
ALREADY ON THE STREET.
>> STAGGERING NUMBERS.
THANK YOU, PIERRE.
>>> LET'S GO TO TIMES SQUARE IN
NEW YORK AND SAM CHAMPION WITH A
FINAL LOOK AT THE DAY'S WEATHER.
SAM?
>> GOOD MORNING, JOSH.
A STORM CYCLE INTO THE DEEP
SOUTH TODAY.
LIKELY TO KICK UP POWERFUL
THUNDERSTORMS.
THE POSSIBILITY IN THE RED ZONE
OF ONE OR TWO SCATTERED
TORNADOES.
LOUISVILLE, NASHVILLE, ATLANTA,
COLUMBIA.
BIRMINGHAM, TALLAHASSEE, YOU'RE
LIKELY TO SEE THE MOST POWERFUL
STORMS COME OUT OF THIS.
WE HAVE A BIG STORM SYSTEM LINED
UP COMING ALL THE WAY ACROSS THE
COUNTRY.
IT WILL BRING IN MUCH COOLER
AIR.
WE HAVE BLIZZARD CONDITIONS
GOING ON IN THE CASCADES RIGHT
NOW.
THIS IS COLD AIR AND EVEN THE
POSSIBILITY OF SNOW.
WATCH THE TEMPERATURE GO DOWN.
MINNEAPOLIS, 18 BY THE TIME WE
GET TO THURSDAY.
WE GO FROM 49 IN SALT LAKE CITY
INTO THE 20s BY THURSDAY.
DENVER, 60 TODAY, 28 BY
THURSDAY.
THIS IS REALLY GOING TO MAKE AN
IMPACT ON THE COLD AIR MOVING
ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
A QUICK LOOK AT THE BIG BOARD.
THE RAIN AND SNOW IN THE
NORTHWEST TODAY.
SUNNY AND DRY THROUGH THE MIDDLE
OF THE COUNTRY.
THAT'S YOUR STORM ZONE.
WE CANNOT FORGET THAT NEW
HAMPSHIRE, ALL THE WAY INTO
MAINE, AND VERMONT, COMING UP
WITH SNOW AND ICE AS WELL TODAY.
THERE IS PLENTY OF WEATHER TO
TALK ABOUT ON THE BOARD ALL WEEK
LONG.
NORTHWEST IS LIKELY TO BE A
SNOWMAKER FROM DENVER TO CHICAGO
BY THE TIME WE GET TO WEDNESDAY
INTO THURSDAY.
JOSH?
>> THANK YOU, SAM.
>>> COMING UP, HOW FAITH IS
HELPING THE FAMILY HOOK FAMILIES
HEAL.
A CONVERSATION WITH THE
RELIGIOUS LEADERS HERE IN
NEWTOWN.
ñ
>>> AS YOU MIGHT IMAGINE, THE
SHATTERED COMMUNITY IS TURNING
TO RELIGIOUS LEADERS FOR COMFORT
AS THEY STRUGGLE TO UNDERSTAND
WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
I'M JOINED BY THREE OF THOSE
LEADERS.
REVEREND MATT, BISHOP RED
KELLER.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
MATT, LET ME BEGIN WITH ROW.
I WAS STRUCK BY YOUR OPENING
WORDS.
AT THE INTERFAITH SERVICE LAST
NIGHT WHEN YOU TOLD EVERYONE,
NOT ONLY HERE IN NEWTOWN BUT
ACROSS THE COUNTRY, WE NEEDED
THIS.
>> MM-HMM.
YES, I THINK IT WAS CLEAR TO US
AS CLERGY AND CLEAR AS PART OF
ALL OUR TRADITIONS THAT OF THE
IMPORTANCE OF GATHERING TOGETHER
TO GRIEVE.
AND THAT THERE IS -- THERE IS
THAT NEEDED CONNECTION WITH
OTHER PEOPLE.
WHO ARE IN THE MIDST OF TRYING
TO COME TO TERMS WITH THINGS
THAT ARE NEARLY IMPOSSIBLE TO
DOM TE
COME TO TERMS WITH.
>> WE COULD FEEL THE PAIN IN THE
ROOM.
HEARD THE SOBS.
RABBI, YOU HAVE HAD TO DEAL
DIRECTLY WITH FAMILY WHO LOST A
LITTLE BOY, NOAH POZNER IN THE
FIRST GRADE.
YOU HAVE A VERY STRIKING PHRASE
TO DESCRIBE WHAT YOU TRIED TO
BRING TO THE FAMILY.
SPIRITUAL MORPHINE.
>> THERE'S PAIN IN THE BODY AND
PAIN OF THE SOUL.
THIS IS REALLY PAINFUL.
FAMILIES JUST DON'T KNOW WHAT TO
DO WITH THEMSELVES.
YOU KNOW.
THEY WANT --
>> WHAT CAN YOU POSSIBLY TELL
THEM?
>> YOU HAVE TO SEE WHAT
RESONATES WITH THE PERSON.
EVERYBODY IS DIFFERENT.
THE POZNERS APPRECIATED THE
THEOLOGICAL UNDERSTANDING OF IT.
BASICALLY, WHAT I ASKED
VERONIQUE IS WHERE IS YOUR
6-YEAR-OLD?
SHE SAID, WHAT YOU  WHAT DO YOU?
SHE SAI
I SAID, WHERE IS YOUR
6-YEAR-OLD?
SHE SAID, WHAT?
>> SAID DID YOUR 6-YEAR-OLD DIE?
SHE SAID NO, IT'S WITHIN ME.
LIKE THAT RUSSIAN DOLL.
IT WAS SOMETHING SHE COULD HOLD
TO THAT WAS LOGICAL.
>> BISHOP, WE'VE BEEN SO
IMPRESSED BY YOUR CONGREGANT,
ROBBIE PARKER, WHO LOST HIS
DAUGHTER, EMILIE, PESPEAKING ABT
HER, SHARING THE LOVE THEY HAD
TOGETHER.
>> YEAH, ROBBIE IS JUST
NATURALLY THAT WAY.
HE ES SPOUSES THE TEACHINGS OF
JESUS CHRIST.
THAT'S ALLOWED HIM TO SHOW LOVE
FOR HIS FAMILY AND THOSE AROUND
HIM.
>> REACHING OUT IN WHAT MUST
HAVE BEEN THE HARDEST THING IN
THE WORLD.
REACHING OUT TO THE FAMILY OF
THE SHOOTER.
>> HE KNOWS THAT IF HE ALLOWS
HATE TO ENTER HIS HEART, THERE'S
NO ROOM FOR LIGHT AND LOVE AND
CARING.
THAT'S JUST NOT WHO HE IS.
>> MATT, HOW CAN A PARENT -- I
MEAN -- I KNOW THAT IS THE
ADMIRABLE THING.
HOW CAN A PARENT NOT HATE IN A
MOMENT LIKE THIS?
>> WELL, I THINK -- EACH FAMILY,
EACH PARENT, EACH INDIVIDUAL IS
GOING TO RESPOND DIFFERENTLY IN
THE MIDST OF THEIR GRIEF.
I THINK WE HAVE TO ALLOW PEOPLE
TO FEEL THEIR ANGER AND NOT TO
KIND OF JUST SAY, NO, YOU CAN'T
FEEL THAT.
I THINK WE DO UNDERGIRD THEM,
FOR US, AS CHRISTIANS, THE
TEACHINGS OF JESUS CHRIST ABOUT
HOW WE LOVE OUR ENEMIES, EVEN
THOSE WHO PERSECUTE US.
WE DON'T SAY THAT'S HOW YOUR
IMMEDIATELY GOING TO RESPOND.
THAT PUTTING TOGETHER MAY TAKE A
LIFETIME FOR SOME PEOPLE.
WE DON'T JUST IMPOSE THAT ON THE
GRIEF PROCESS.
THERE ARE FOLKS, EXPERIENCING
THAT, IS A TESTIMONY OF A SPIRIT
OF FOLKS THAT CAN DO THAT.
IT DOESN'T MEAN EVERYBODY IS
ABLE TO DO THAT IN THAT MOMENT.
>> I CAN IMAGINE THE OPPOSITE,
R
RAB
RABBI.
I CAN IMAGINE A PARENT SAYING
THERE IS NO WAY A GOOD AND
LOVING GOD COULD ALLOW THIS.
THEREFORE, GOD MUST NOT EXIST.
HOW DO YOU DEAL WITH FAMILIES
STRUGGLING WITH THEIR FAITH?
>> THIS IS NOT AN ACT OF GOD.
THIS IS AN ACT OF MAN.
IF WE HAVE FREE WILL, THERE'S
THE OPPORTUNITY TO ACT BADLY.
I HEARD FROM FRIEND WHO IS GREW
UP WITH THE KILLER ADAM THAT HE
WAS BULLIED IN SCHOOL A GREAT
DEAL.
AND THAT DOESN'T EXCUSE HIM.
I'M JUST TALKING BECAUSE I DO
WANT TO TALK ABOUT THE CULTURE
OF PEACE.
AND PEACEFUL CLASSROOMS.
AND -- I JUST BRING THAT OUT
THERE THAT THERE IS A -- A
CERTAIN PATHWAY, THE WAY THAT
GOT SO TWISTED.
DOESN'T EXCUSE THE CRIMES.
WE NEED TO LOOK THAT, TOO.
>> WE NEED TO LOOK THAT,
STRUGGLE FOR SOLUTIONS TOGETHER.
YOU ALL SET SUCH A FINE EXAMPLE
LAST NIGHT WITH THE INTERFAITH
SERVICE.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR THAT.
>>> WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH THE
YOUNG PEOPLE'S CHORUS IN NEW
YORK CITY.
♪ THERE'S A PLACE A PLACE FOR
US ♪
♪ HOLD MY HAND AND I'LL TAKE YOU
>>> IT'S PROBABLY NOT AN XRAJS
TO SAY THAT ALMOST NERVE THIS
COUNTRY IS THINK OF THE FAMILY,
THE VICTIM, THE SURVIVORS OF
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WHAT BETTER WAY TO HONOR THEM
THAN BY A SPECIAL PERFORMANCE OF
THE YOUNG PEOPLE'S CHORUS OF NEW
YORK CITY.
HERE THEY ARE SINGING AMAZING
GRACE.
♪ AMAZING GRACE HOW SWEET THE
SOUND THAT SAVED A CHILD LIKE  E
ME ♪
♪ I ONCE WAS LOST BUT NOW AM
FOUND WAS BLIND BUT NOW I SEE ♪
♪ TWAS GRACE THAT TAUGHT MY
HEART TO FEEL AND GRACE MY FEARS
RELIEVED ♪
♪ HOW PRECIOUS THIS THAT GRACE
APPEARED THE HOUR I FIRST
BELIEVED ♪
♪ AMAZING GRACE HOW SWEET THE
SOUND THAT SAVED A CHILD LIKE
ME ♪
♪ I ONCE WAS LOST BUT NOW AM
FOUND WAS BLIND BUT NOW I SEE ♪
♪
♪ AS GRACE LEADS ME HOME
♪ AMAZING GRACE HOW SWEET THE
SOUND THAT SAVED A CHILD LIKE
ME ♪
♪ I ONCE WAS LOST BUT NOW AM
FOUND WAS BLIND BUT NOW I SEE ♪
>>> AND THANK YOU FOR JOINING US
THIS MORNING FOR THE BEGINNING
OF THAT CON VER SAGTS, HERE FROM
NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT.
THE NEWTOWN METHODIST CHURCH.
ELIZABETH IS IN NEW YORK.
YOU'RE LISTENING TO THE NEW YORK
CHILDREN'S CHORUS SINGING
"SOMEWHERE OVER THE RAINBOW."
WE'RE GOING TO BE TALKING ALL
THIS WEEK ON OUR PLATFORMS ABOUT
THIS VIOLENCE.
KATIE WILL BE TALKING TO TWO
VICTIMS FROM THE COLUMBINE
SHOOTINGS.
WE LEAVE YOU WITH THE YOUNG
PEOPLE'S CHORUS OF NEW YORK
CITY.
♪ IF HAPPY LITTLE BLUE BIRDS FLY
BEYOND THE RAINBOW WHY OH WHY
CAN'T I ♪
>>> GOOD MORNING, WE HAVE RAIN
IN THE BAY AREA, MIKE NICCO IS
CHECKING OUT LIVE DOPPLER.
>> GOOD MORNING EVERYBODY.
YOU SEE SOME OF THE RADAR
RETURNS IN THE NORTH BAY, HEART
OF THE BAY AND ESPECIALLY DOWN
IN THE SOUTH BAY.
THAT IS WHERE WE'VE SEEN THE
BEST RADAR RETURNS OVER THE LAST
COUPLE OF HOURS.
EVERYBODY HAS BEEN GETTING
DRIZZLE AND LIGHT RAIN UP TO
ABOUT NOON.
THEN WE HAVE ISOLATED SHOWERS
FOR THE AFTERNOON HOURS AND LOW
TO MID 50s.
FROST TUESDAY AND MORE SO
WEDNESDAY MORNING AND THEN THE
STORM DOORS OPEN THURSDAY
THROUGH THE WEEKEND.
>> HEAVY TRAFFIC OUT THERE.
WE ALSO HAVE AN TRAIN 7 DELAY.
SLOW EARLIER ACCIDENT, CLEARED
OUT OF THE LANES BUT THE RED
DOTS, SLOW TRAFFIC REMAIN SOUTH
280 AT OCEAN AN ACCIDENT
ANNOUNCER: IT'S "LIVE WITH KELLY
AND MICHAEL."
TODAY, STAR OF THE NEW FILM
"THIS IS 40," PAUL RUDD.
AND FROM "DJANGO UNCHAINED,"
ACADEMY AWARD WINNING ACTOR
CHRISTOPH WALTZ.
PLUS A LESSON IN HOLIDAY
ETIQUETTE AS WE KICK
COUNTDOWN TO CHRISTMAS WEEK.
ALL NEXT ON THE EMMY-AWARD
WINNING "LIVE."
[CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
DISNEY-ABC DOMESTIC TELEVISION]
ANNOUNCER: NOW HERE ARE