EVER HAD, REALLY.
>> FOR WOMEN, HAIR LOSS IS AN
EMOTIONAL EXPERIENCE AND CAN BE
DUE TO GENETICS, MEDICATIONS,
HORMONES, AND MORE.
AT HAIR CLUB FOR WOMEN, WE
UNDERSTAND THAT AND OFFER MORE
THAN ONE SOLUTION TO YOUR
HAIR LOSS.
>> Announcer: AT HAIR CLUB FOR
WOMEN, OUR CARING CONSULTANTS
MEET WITH YOU ONE-ON-ONE TO
EVALUATE THE LEVEL AND TYPE
OF YOUR HAIR LOSS AND OFFER
A CUSTOMIZED, PROVEN HAIR LOSS
SOLUTION THAT'S JUST RIGHT
FOR YOU.
>> IT'S NOT COSMETIC.
IT'S NOT VANITY.
IT IS A NECESSITY, AND WE ARE
VERY LUCKY AND VERY BLESSED,
I THINK...
>> A BASEBALL HAT IS NOW AN
ACCESSORY, NOT AN NECESSITY.
>> THEY KNOW HOW MUCH THEY'RE
HELPING PEOPLE.
THEY KNOW HOW MUCH THEY'RE
CHANGING LIVES.
>> HEAR, HEAR TO HAIR CLUB.
>> Announcer: HAIR CLUB FOR
WOMEN IS RECOGNIZED THE WORLD
OVER AS THE GOLD STANDARD IN
PROVEN HAIR LOSS SOLUTIONS FOR
30 YEARS, AND YOU WON'T FIND
OUR GROUNDBREAKING TECHNOLOGIES
ANYWHERE ELSE BUT HAIR CLUB.
CALL OUR TOLL-FREE NUMBER NOW
OR VISIT OUR WEBSITE AT
WWW.HAIRCLUB.COM.
WE'LL SEND YOU THIS INFORMATIVE
"FOR WOMEN ONLY" BROCHURE WITH
ALL THE INFORMATION YOU NEED
TO LOOK, FEEL, AND ACT YOUNGER
THAN YOUR YEARS.
AND FOR A LIMITED TIME, WHEN YOU
CALL OR VISIT HAIR CLUB TODAY
FOR YOUR FREE PRIVATE
CONSULTATION, YOU CAN RECEIVE
A MICROSCOPIC HAIR AND SCALP
ANALYSIS ABSOLUTELY FREE.
YOU TOO CAN GO FROM THIS TO THIS
WITH HAIR CLUB FOR WOMEN.
>> WE CALLED HAIR CLUB,
AND WE'RE GLAD WE DID.
[♪..., NO VOICES]
[MUSIC CHANGES]
>> Woman: ♪ OOH... YEAH
♪ YEAH, YEAH, YEAH
[♪...]
>> Announcer: HAIR CLUB--
WE DO IT ALL. FOR YOU.
>> 80% OF FEELING GOOD
IS LOOKING GOOD.
>> I ABSOLUTELY LOVE IT.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
>> YOU FEEL LIKE A NEW
HUMAN BEING.
>> I CAN USE CLIPS AND HEADBANDS
AND BARRETTES, AND IT'S,
IT'S WONDERFUL.
>> I AM MORE PLEASED THAN
WHAT I HAD EVEN IMAGINED.
>> NOW I GO ANYWHERE, DO
ANYTHING, WITH CONFIDENCE.
EVEN ON A REALLY BAD DAY, YOU
NEVER, EVER HAVE A BAD HAIR DAY.
>> I FELT SO GOOD ABOUT MYSELF.
I'VE NEVER FELT BETTER.
>> I LOVE MY HAIR.
I LOVE HOW I FEEL ABOUT MY HAIR.
>> I'M A NEW ME. I'M REINVENTED.
>> HI, I'M TOM WAINMAN, AND
I'M HERE TO TALK TO YOU TODAY
ABOUT A COMPANY THAT HAS HELPED
THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE LOOK
AND FEEL GREAT.
FOR MORE THAN 30 YEARS, HAIR
CLUB HAS OFFERED HAIR LOSS
SOLUTIONS TO MEN AND WOMEN WHO
ARE FED UP WITH THINNING HAIR,
HAIR LOSS, AND THE LOW
SELF-ESTEEM THAT CAN COME
WITH IT.
HAIR CLUB IS THE LEADING
PROVIDER OF PROVEN HAIR LOSS
SOLUTIONS IN NORTH AMERICA.
ALTHOUGH MANY COMPANIES ON TV
AND THE INTERNET CLAIM THEY CAN
REGROW HAIR WITH MIRACLE CURES
OR FOCUS ONLY ON ONE PRODUCT OR
SOLUTION, MOST OF THESE CLAIMS
ARE EITHER BIASED OR UNPROVEN.
HAIR CLUB IS NOT ABOUT ONE
PRODUCT, ONE SHAMPOO, OR A
MIRACLE CURE.
HAIR CLUB IS ABOUT ALL PROVEN
HAIR LOSS SOLUTIONS.
HAIR CLUB IS A REAL COMPANY,
AND THEY GUARANTEE THEIR WORK.
HAIR CLUB'S STAFF INCLUDE
PROMINENT, BOARD-CERTIFIED
DOCTORS, RESEARCHERS,
WORLD-CLASS HAIRSTYLISTS, AND
TRAINED HAIR LOSS CONSULTANTS--
EXPERTS.
REAL PEOPLE WHO LOVE WHAT THEY
DO AND ASPIRE TO HELP OTHERS.
DURING THIS SHOW, YOU'LL MEET
THESE UNIQUE INDIVIDUALS.
MOST IMPORTANT, YOU'LL MEET REAL
CLIENTS WHO, LIKE MANY OF YOU,
WANTED TO DO SOMETHING ABOUT
THEIR HAIR LOSS.
ARE YOU READY TO DO SOMETHING
ABOUT YOUR THINNING HAIR?
IF YOU'RE READY TO ACT OR EVEN
JUST FIND OUT MORE ABOUT HAIR
LOSS, HAIR CLUB IS READY
TO HELP.
STAY TUNED AND YOU'LL LEARN MORE
ABOUT THIS UNIQUE COMPANY AND
THE THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE HAIR
CLUB HAS HELPED TO GET THEIR
HAIR BACK.
>> I WANTED TO PROJECT MYSELF
IN THE VERY BEST POSSIBLE WAY.
I DECIDED THAT HAVING MY HAIR
BACK THE WAY IT USED TO BE WAS
AN IMPORTANT STEP FOR ME.
>> MYSELF, I'M 45 YEARS OLD, AND
YOU KNOW, I'M NOT IN THE BEST
SHAPE IN THE WORLD, BUT ONE
THING, I'M CONTINUALLY TRYING
TO GET BETTER, AND MY HAIR IS
JUST ONE LESS PROBLEM I EVER
HAVE TO THINK ABOUT.
>> I FEEL BLESSED.
I'M NOT WORRIED ABOUT OTHER
PEOPLE PASSING JUDGMENT OR
WONDERING WHAT MIGHT BE WRONG
WITH ME.
I DON'T SECOND-GUESS GOING TO
THE STORE OR GOING TO THE MOVIES
OR GOING TO HAVE A DRINK.
I'M CONFIDENT. I'M COMFORTABLE.
>> WELCOME BACK.
LET'S GET RIGHT TO THE ROOT
OF THE PROBLEM-- HAIR LOSS
AND WHAT CAUSES IT.
NOW, HAIR LOSS AFFECTS MORE THAN
70 MILLION PEOPLE IN NORTH
AMERICA TODAY-- 40 MILLION MEN
AND 30 MILLION WOMEN.
THAT'S A LOT OF PEOPLE.
SOME PEOPLE TRY PRODUCTS THAT
CLAIM TO REGROW HAIR ONLY TO
FIND OUT A FEW HUNDRED DOLLARS
LATER THAT THEY DIDN'T WORK.
DON'T WASTE YOUR MONEY
ON UNPROVEN REMEDIES.
IF YOU CARE ABOUT HOW YOU LOOK
AND YOU WANT TO GET YOUR HAIR
BACK, TAKE TIME TO LISTEN TO
WORLD-RENOWNED HAIR LOSS EXPERT
DR. JON GAFFNEY, MEDICAL
DIRECTOR OF HAIR CLUB, A
BOARD-CERTIFIED PLASTIC SURGEON,
AND MEMBER OF THE AMERICAN
MEDICAL ASSOCIATION.
>> HAIR LOSS FOR BOTH MEN AND
WOMEN IS MORE COMMON THAN YOU
THINK.
BY THE AGE OF 50, HALF THE
ADULT POPULATION EXPERIENCES
HAIR LOSS.
MANY OF US IN THE MEDICAL
COMMUNITY EXPECT THIS TREND TO
INCREASE OVER TIME, IN PART DUE
TO SUCH THINGS AS STRESS,
POOR NUTRITION, FAD DIETS, AND
CERTAIN PRESCRIPTION MEDICATION.
HAIR LOSS IS DIFFERENT
FOR MEN AND WOMEN.
MALE PATTERN HAIR LOSS IS THE
MOST COMMON HAIR LOSS FOR MEN,
REPRESENTING MORE THAN 90% OF
ALL MALE CASES IN NORTH AMERICA.
IT OCCURS DUE TO THE CHEMICAL
DIHYDROTESTOSTERONE, COMMONLY
KNOWN AS D.H.T.
D.H.T. CAUSES A SHORTENING
OF THE LIFESPAN OF THE HAIR
FOLLICLES IN THESE MEN.
THE FOLLICLES RESISTANCE TO
D.H.T., OR LACK THEREOF, IS
GENETIC, AND THAT'S WHY SOME MEN
GO BALD AND SOME DON'T.
>> FOR ME, I STARTED TO GO BALD
WHEN I WAS IN HIGH SCHOOL.
IT WAS A LITTLE BIT AT THE
BEGINNING, AND THEN IT GOT
REALLY WORSE ONCE I GOT INTO
COLLEGE, AND TO THE POINT WHERE
IT WAS REALLY DRAMATIC.
AND THROUGH THIS TIME, I STARTED
TO USE A LOT OF DIFFERENT
PRODUCTS, A LOT OF DIFFERENT
THINGS THAT PROMISED, YOU KNOW,
REGROWING OF HAIR, THINGS OF
THAT NATURE.
>> HAIR LOSS FOR WOMEN, IN MANY
WAYS, IS FAR MORE TRAUMATIC.
THE PSYCHOLOGICAL EFFECTS FOR
WOMEN CAN BE DEVASTATING.
THERE ARE MANY DIFFERENT CAUSES
OF HAIR LOSS AMONG WOMEN.
FEMALE PATTERN THINNING, WHICH
IS GENETIC DIFFUSE HAIR LOSS,
MENOPAUSE-RELATED, POSTPARTUM,
OR STRESS-RELATED SHEDDING, AND
ALOPECIA AREATA, OR SPOTTY HAIR
LOSS, ARE JUST A FEW.
SOME HAIR LOSS IN WOMEN IS
CAUSED BY POOR HAIR CARE.
HARSH CHEMICAL RELAXERS OR TIGHT
HAIR BRAIDING CAN PERMANENTLY
DAMAGE THESE HAIR FOLLICLES.
>> YOU KNOW, A WOMAN LOSING
HER HAIR HAS TO BE THE MOST
DIFFICULT THING IN THE WORLD.
YOU KNOW, YOU EXPECT MEN TO
LOSE THEIR HAIR, BUT NOT WOMEN,
RIGHT?
IT'S VERY UNBECOMING.
IT'S EMBARRASSING.
YOU LOSE YOUR SELF-ESTEEM.
I MEAN, I DID THE WEAVE THING.
THEN YOU GET THE WIGS.
GUESS WHAT.
YOU'RE VERY UNCOMFORTABLE
GOING OUT.
IT'S A WINDY DAY.
YOU DON'T KNOW IF IT'S
GONNA BLOW OFF.
I'M A PROFUSE SWEATER, RIGHT?
IT COULD JUST SLIDE OFF.
THEN YOU PICK UP A KID.
THEY GRAB IT, IT MOVES.
IT'S LIKE, ENOUGH ALREADY.
THERE HAS GOT TO BE
SOMETHING BETTER.
>> THERE IS AN OLD EXPRESSION
THAT SAYS, "IF THE ONLY TOOL YOU
HAVE IS A HAMMER, THEN ALL THE
WORLD LOOKS LIKE A NAIL."
HAIR CLUB IS NOT ABOUT
ONE TOOL.
IT'S ABOUT ALL PROVEN
HAIR LOSS SOLUTIONS.
>> THAT WAS DR. JON GAFFNEY,
WORLD-RENOWNED HAIR LOSS EXPERT.
NOW WE'LL SHOW YOU HOW YOU CAN
GET YOUR HAIR BACK WITH PROVEN
HAIR LOSS SOLUTIONS.
>> Announcer: DON'T TOLERATE
ANOTHER DAY OF HAIR LOSS OR
THINNING HAIR.
BECAUSE NOW THE SOLUTION YOU
NEED TO GET A FULLER, NATURAL
HEAD OF HAIR IS JUST ONE PHONE
CALL AWAY.
HAIR CLUB IS THE ONLY COMPANY
IN THE WORLD TO OFFER ALL TESTED
AND PROVEN HAIR LOSS SOLUTIONS,
BECAUSE NO SINGLE SOLUTION
IS RIGHT FOR EVERY TYPE
OF HAIR LOSS.
CALL HAIR CLUB NOW FOR THIS FREE
EDUCATIONAL BOOKLET AND GET A
FREE MICROSCOPIC HAIR AND SCALP
ANALYSIS AT ANY OF OUR HAIR CLUB
CENTERS NATIONWIDE.
YOUNG OR OLD, MAN OR WOMAN,
NO MATTER WHAT KIND OF HAIR LOSS
YOU MAY HAVE, HAIR CLUB HAS
A UNIQUE SOLUTION FOR YOU,
GUARANTEED.
NO OTHER COMPANY ON THE PLANET
CAN MAKE THAT CLAIM.
HAIR CLUB HAS BEEN THE
RECOGNIZED LEADER IN HAIR LOSS
SOLUTIONS FOR OVER 30 YEARS,
WITH CENTERS IN OVER 90
LOCATIONS AND OVER 50,000
SATISFIED CLIENTS.
CALL NOW AND GET THE FACTS.
HAIR CLUB'S NEW BREAKTHROUGH
EDUCATIONAL BOOKLET IS
YOURS FREE.
THIS VITAL NEW INFORMATION
ENDORSED BY PROMINENT PHYSICIANS
CAN CHANGE YOUR LIFE.
PICK UP THE PHONE RIGHT NOW
AND WE'LL RUSH IT TO YOU FREE
WITH ABSOLUTELY NO OBLIGATION.
AS AN ADDED BONUS, WE'LL ALSO
GIVE YOU A FREE, PRIVATE, AND
CONFIDENTIAL MICROSCOPIC HAIR
AND SCALP ANALYSIS.
THIS IS A $150 VALUE, BUT IT'S
YOURS FREE IF YOU CALL
RIGHT NOW.
THIS OFFER IS FOR A LIMITED
TIME ONLY.
DON'T TOLERATE HAIR LOSS
ANOTHER DAY.
LOOK YOUNGER AND FEEL
MORE CONFIDENT.
TAKE ON THE WORLD LIKE
YOUR OLD SELF.
CALL NOW AND CHANGE
YOUR LIFE FOREVER.
HAIR CLUB-- WE DO IT ALL.
FOR YOU.
[♪...]
>> WHEN I FIRST GOT MY HAIR, I
COULDN'T BELIEVE THE DIFFERENCE
IT MADE.
I FELT SO GOOD ABOUT MYSELF.
I'VE NEVER FELT BETTER.
>> SOME PEOPLE DIDN'T EVEN
NOTICE I HAD ANYTHING DONE.
THEY JUST SAID, "YOU LOOK GOOD,
YOU LOOK YOUNGER," AND IT'S JUST
A PLEASANT EXPERIENCE ALL THE
WAY AROUND.
>> IT LOOKED SO NATURAL TO ME,
SO I WENT AND CHECKED IT OUT,
MADE THE PHONE CALL, AND IT
REALLY CHANGED MY LIFE.
>> I DON'T SECOND-GUESS GOING TO
THE STORE OR GOING TO THE MOVIES
OR GOING TO HAVE A DRINK.
I'M CONFIDENT. I'M COMFORTABLE.
>> NOW LET'S TALK ABOUT THE
PROVEN SOLUTIONS AVAILABLE TO
YOU AT HAIR CLUB AND THE HAIR
CLUB GUARANTEE OF SATISFACTION.
WHAT IS PROVEN TO WORK?
HAIR CLUB HAS EXPERTISE IN
THREE AREAS: NON-SURGICAL HAIR
ENHANCEMENT, F.D.A.-APPROVED
HAIR THERAPIES, AND MICROSCOPIC
FOLLICULAR UNIT HAIR
TRANSPLANTS.
AVAILABLE ONLY AT HAIR CLUB,
THE BIOMATRIX STRAND-BY-STRAND
PROCESS IS KNOWN AROUND THE
WORLD AS THE GOLD STANDARD
IN HAIR REPLACEMENT.
HAIR CLUB'S GROUNDBREAKING
TECHNOLOGY IS THE ONLY PROCESS
AVAILABLE TO DATE THAT GIVES YOU
A FULL, HEALTHY-LOOKING HEAD OF
HAIR BY ADDING REAL HUMAN HAIR
TO YOUR OWN HAIR.
BIOMATRIX IS NOT A TOUPEE.
IT'S NOT A WIG.
IT'S A CUSTOM-MADE BLEND OF
YOUR OWN HAIR WITH REAL HUMAN
HAIR THAT IS MATCHED TO YOUR
INDIVIDUAL REQUIREMENTS.
THAT INCLUDES HAIR COLOR, FACIAL
STRUCTURE, AND SKIN TONE.
THE PROCESS IS NATURAL AND
VIRTUALLY UNDETECTABLE.
WHEN YOU BRUSH YOUR HAIR,
IT ALL BLENDS TOGETHER.
IF SOMEONE TOUCHES YOUR HAIR,
IT FEELS NORMAL.
IT'S EASY TO STYLE.
YOU CAN ROUGH IT UP.
YOU CAN GO SWIMMING, BIKING,
JOGGING, OR ANYWHERE LIFE TAKES
YOU, AND YOU WILL LOOK GREAT.
>> I CAN SWIM, I BIKE, HIKE,
I DO EVERYTHING, AND THE KEY
POINT HERE IS NO ONE HAS
NOTICED.
EVERYBODY THINKS I LOOK BETTER,
BUT THEY CAN'T QUITE PUT THEIR
FINGER ON IT.
SO WHEN THEY TOLD ME THAT WOULD
HAPPEN, I DIDN'T BELIEVE IT.
I THOUGHT EVERYBODY WOULD NOTICE
RIGHT AWAY, BUT THEY DIDN'T.
THEY JUST THOUGHT, "WELL,
YOUR HAIR'S DIFFERENT.
WHAT'D YOU DO?"
AND SO I JUST, YOU KNOW, IN SOME
CASES... PEOPLE THAT WERE CLOSE
TO ME, I TOLD THEM.
OTHER PEOPLE, I JUST
LET THEM GUESS.
AND SO I THINK THAT'S IMPORTANT
FOR WOMEN, ESPECIALLY, TO KNOW
IS THAT YOU'RE GONNA LOOK GREAT,
YOU'RE GONNA FEEL GREAT.
>> I DIDN'T WANT TO BE ONE OF
THOSE GUYS THAT YOU WALK DOWN
THE STREET AND SAY, "HEY, BUDDY,
NICE HAIR!
WHO SHOT THE MANNEQUIN?"
YOU KNOW, THAT KIND OF THING,
IT JUST DIDN'T FLY FOR ME.
IT WAS VERY IMPORTANT THAT
IT BE UNDETECTABLE.
>> WE ARE VERY LUCKY TODAY
TO GROW UP AT A TIME WHERE
TECHNOLOGY IS AS ADVANCED
AS IT IS.
I'VE HAD A CHANCE TO REPLACE MY
HAIR WITH A TECHNOLOGY THAT IS
UNBELIEVABLE, AND I'M VERY
HAPPY THAT I DID IT.
>> PEOPLE THINK THAT I HAVE
PROBABLY FOUND SOME MAGIC
OINTMENT OR SOMETHING, RIGHT?
THEY HAVE NO IDEA THAT I'VE
ACTUALLY GONE TO HAIR CLUB.
I HAVE, IN FACT, SHARED IT
WITH SOME, BUT NOT MANY, RIGHT,
BECAUSE I LIKE TO KEEP
'EM GUESSING.
DO YOU REALIZE HOW NICE IT IS
FOR SOMEONE TO WALK UP TO YOU
AND SAY, "MY GOD, YOU HAVE THE
MOST BEAUTIFUL HEAD OF HAIR"?
AND I SAY, "THANK YOU."
>> HAIR CLUB IS ALSO A LEADER IN
HAIR THERAPIES, WITH ITS EXTREME
HAIR THERAPY PROGRAM.
>> Dr. Gaffney: THE E.X.T.
PROGRAM AND PRODUCT REGIMEN
INCLUDES HIGH-QUALITY SHAMPOOS,
CLEANSERS, AND CONDITIONERS, AS
WELL AS THE F.D.A.-APPROVED
HAIR REGROWTH AGENT, MINOXIDIL.
IT IS AN EXCELLENT PROGRAM FOR
MEN AND WOMEN IN THE EARLY
STAGES OF HAIR LOSS, AND HAS
BEEN PROVEN TO WORK FOR MANY
PEOPLE.
THE SUCCESS OF THE PROGRAM
DEPENDS ON YOUR LEVEL AND TYPE
OF HAIR LOSS.
I RECOMMEND YOU HAVE A
CONSULTATION AT HAIR CLUB TO
DETERMINE WHETHER OR NOT YOU
ARE A GOOD E.X.T. CANDIDATE.
>> HAIR CLUB ALSO OFFERS IN
SELECT AREAS THE GOLD STANDARD
IN HAIR TRANSPLANTATION--
MICROSCOPIC FOLLICULAR UNIT
HAIR TRANSPLANTS.
IT'S NATURAL, PERMANENT, AND
YOUR TRANSPLANTED HAIR IS
GUARANTEED TO GROW THE WAY
MOTHER NATURE PROGRAMMED IT TO.
>> IF YOU ARE A HAIR TRANSPLANT
CANDIDATE, WHEN CHOOSING A HAIR
TRANSPLANT PHYSICIAN, THE THREE
MOST IMPORTANT ASPECTS YOU
MUST CONSIDER ARE ARTISTRY,
EXPERIENCE, AND PATIENT CARE.
HAIR CLUB'S PHYSICIANS ARE
HIGHLY EXPERIENCED ARTISTS,
HAVING PERFORMED MORE THAN
50,000 PROCEDURES, AND PATIENT
CARE AT HAIR CLUB IS PARAMOUNT.
>> WHEN YOU ACTUALLY SEE THE
HAIR GROW, YOU'RE AMAZED.
YOU'RE WATCHING IT GROW DAY BY
DAY FROM A THINNER LOOK TO A
FULLER LOOK TILL YOU CAN THEN
DO THE THINGS THAT YOU'VE ALWAYS
WANTED TO DO WITH YOUR HAIR,
USING DIFFERENT PRODUCTS AND
STYLING YOUR HAIR DIFFERENTLY.
>> I FINALLY WENT TO THE HAIR
CLUB, AND I FOUND THAT THEY HAD
THE BEST TECHNOLOGY AND THEY
WERE FAR SUPERIOR THAN EVERYONE
ELSE.
THEY TREATED ME LIKE FAMILY,
LIKE I WAS SOMEBODY IMPORTANT.
I DECIDED TO GO WITH THEM,
AND THE RESULTS SPEAK FOR
THEMSELVES.
PEOPLE WILL JUST KIND OF
LOOK AT YOU AND WONDER,
"WHAT'S GOING ON," YOU KNOW,
"THIS GUY'S LOOKING YOUNGER AND
YOUNGER," AND I'M FEEING BETTER
AND BETTER ABOUT IT, AND IT
JUST, IT'S A GREAT FEELING.
>> HAIR CLUB IS THE ONLY COMPANY
THAT OFFERS ALL PROVEN HAIR LOSS
SOLUTIONS BACKED BY A GUARANTEE
OF SATISFACTION.
IF YOU ARE NOT 100% SATISFIED
WITH THE OPTION YOU'VE CHOSEN,
HAIR CLUB WILL APPLY YOUR
INITIAL PURCHASE PRICE TO ANY
OF ITS OTHER PROVEN HAIR LOSS
SOLUTIONS.
HAIR CLUB HAS CHANGED
MANY PEOPLE'S LIVES.
YOU MIGHT NOT KNOW IT NOW,
BUT I USED TO HAVE A HAIR LOSS
PROBLEM.
IS YOUR HAIR LOSS BOTHERING YOU?
MAYBE IT'S TIME YOU DID
SOMETHING ABOUT IT.
WHEN WE COME BACK, WE'LL
INTRODUCE THE PEOPLE WHO CAN
HELP YOU FIND THE RIGHT
SOLUTION.
>> Announcer: DON'T TOLERATE
ANOTHER DAY OF HAIR LOSS OR
THINNING HAIR.
BECAUSE NOW THE SOLUTION YOU
NEED TO GET A FULLER, NATURAL
HEAD OF HAIR IS JUST ONE
PHONE CALL AWAY.
HAIR CLUB IS THE ONLY COMPANY
IN THE WORLD TO OFFER ALL TESTED
AND PROVEN HAIR LOSS SOLUTIONS,
BECAUSE NO SINGLE SOLUTION
IS RIGHT FOR EVERY TYPE
OF HAIR LOSS.
CALL HAIR CLUB NOW FOR THIS FREE
EDUCATIONAL BOOKLET AND GET A
FREE MICROSCOPIC HAIR AND SCALP
ANALYSIS AT ANY OF OUR HAIR CLUB
CENTERS NATIONWIDE.
YOUNG OR OLD, MAN OR WOMAN,
NO MATTER WHAT KIND OF HAIR LOSS
YOU MAY HAVE, HAIR CLUB HAS
A UNIQUE SOLUTION FOR YOU,
GUARANTEED.
NO OTHER COMPANY ON THE PLANET
CAN MAKE THAT CLAIM.
HAIR CLUB HAS BEEN THE
RECOGNIZED LEADER IN HAIR LOSS
SOLUTIONS FOR OVER 30 YEARS,
WITH CENTERS IN OVER 90
LOCATIONS AND OVER 50,000
SATISFIED CLIENTS.
CALL NOW AND GET THE FACTS.
HAIR CLUB'S NEW BREAKTHROUGH
EDUCATIONAL BOOKLET IS
YOURS FREE.
THIS VITAL NEW INFORMATION
ENDORSED BY PROMINENT PHYSICIANS
CAN CHANGE YOUR LIFE.
PICK UP THE PHONE RIGHT NOW
AND WE'LL RUSH IT TO YOU FREE
WITH ABSOLUTELY NO OBLIGATION.
AS AN ADDED BONUS, WE'LL ALSO
GIVE YOU A FREE, PRIVATE, AND
CONFIDENTIAL MICROSCOPIC
HAIR AND SCALP ANALYSIS.
THIS IS A $150 VALUE, BUT IT'S
YOURS FREE IF YOU CALL
RIGHT NOW.
THIS OFFER IS FOR A LIMITED
TIME ONLY.
DON'T TOLERATE HAIR LOSS
ANOTHER DAY.
LOOK YOUNGER AND FEEL
MORE CONFIDENT.
TAKE ON THE WORLD LIKE
YOUR OLD SELF.
CALL NOW AND CHANGE
YOUR LIFE FOREVER.
HAIR CLUB-- WE DO IT ALL.
FOR YOU.
[♪...]
>> YOU'VE HEARD FROM
THE EXPERTS.
YOU'VE HEARD FROM THE CLIENTS.
SO LET'S TALK ABOUT ANOTHER
ASPECT OF HAIR CLUB THAT TRULY
MAKES THIS COMPANY UNIQUE--
ITS STAFF.
AT HAIR CLUB, YOU'LL MEET A
CARING STAFF THAT WILL HELP YOU
THROUGH ALL ASPECTS OF HAIR
RESTORATION, FROM INFORMATIVE
CONSULTANTS TO HAIR LOSS EXPERTS
TO WORLD-CLASS HAIRSTYLISTS.
HAIR CLUB IS THE ONLY COMPANY
THAT OFFERS ALL PROVEN HAIR LOSS
SOLUTIONS BACKED BY A GUARANTEE
OF SATISFACTION.
>> AFTER PEOPLE GET THEIR HAIR,
YOU CAN REALLY SEE THE CHANGE
IN THEM.
YOU SEE A CONFIDENCE, NEWFOUND
CONFIDENCE THAT PEOPLE OFTEN
HAVE.
>> WHEN YOU HAVE A FULL HEAD
OF HAIR, THERE'S A LOT YOU
CAN DO WITH IT.
YOU CAN SHAMPOO YOUR HAIR,
CONDITION IT, BLOW IT DRY, AND
ALSO CURL, IRON, AND STYLE
YOUR HAIR.
>> THEY WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT
YOU WALK OUT OF THERE COMPLETELY
SATISFIED AND COMFORTABLE, AND
THEY WANT YOU TO BE ABLE TO SAY,
"HEY, YOU KNOW, THIS IS ME.
I GOT A FULL HEAD OF HAIR,
AND I FEEL GREAT."
>> I'M AN EXPERT BECAUSE I ALSO
SUFFER FROM HAIR LOSS AND I HAVE
BEEN THROUGH ALL THE EMOTIONS.
I'VE EXPERIENCED IT FROM THE
TIME I WAS A CHILD UNTIL I FOUND
MY SOLUTION AT THE HAIR CLUB.
I AM PASSIONATE ABOUT WHAT I DO.
>> THE WAY THAT I WAS TREATED
WAS OUTSTANDING, AND ONE OF MY
MAIN GREAT EXPERIENCES IS
THE WAY THEY TREATED ME.
MY HAIRSTYLIST AND I WERE
ABLE TO VIBE, WE WERE ABLE
TO COMMUNICATE.
SHE KNEW EXACTLY WHAT I WANTED.
>> I'M HERE TO TELL YOU THAT
IT'S A WONDERFUL EXPERIENCE.
PEOPLE WERE VERY KIND,
VERY SENSITIVE.
>> YOU KNOW, THIS IS REALLY
A PERSONAL THING.
I MEAN, THE HAIR CLUB, THEY TAKE
THE TIME TO LISTEN AND THEY TAKE
THE TIME TO GET IT RIGHT.
>> HAIR CLUB WILL LAY OUT ALL
THE SOLUTIONS, AND THEY'LL DO
WHAT'S RIGHT FOR YOU.
AS A MATTER OF FACT, YOU'LL MAKE
THE DECISION WHAT YOU WANT
TO DO.
>> I BELIEVE THAT THE HAIR CLUB
HAS THE BEST SOLUTION FOR ANYONE
THAT IS SUFFERING WITH HAIR
LOSS.
>> I LOVE WORKING AT HAIR CLUB.
IT'S REALLY AN INCREDIBLE JOB.
TO COME TO WORK EVER DAY AND
REALLY HELP PEOPLE AND SEE THESE
TRANSFORMATIONS IN PEOPLE,
IT'S AMAZING, I LOVE IT.
>> NOW WE'LL SHOW YOU HOW YOU
CAN GET YOUR HAIR BACK WITH
PROVEN HAIR LOSS SOLUTIONS.
>> Announcer: DON'T TOLERATE
ANOTHER DAY OF HAIR LOSS OR
THINNING HAIR.
BECAUSE NOW THE SOLUTION YOU
NEED TO GET A FULLER, NATURAL
HEAD OF HAIR IS JUST ONE
PHONE CALL AWAY.
HAIR CLUB IS THE ONLY COMPANY
IN THE WORLD TO OFFER ALL TESTED
AND PROVEN HAIR LOSS SOLUTIONS,
BECAUSE NO SINGLE SOLUTION
IS RIGHT FOR EVERY TYPE
OF HAIR LOSS.
CALL HAIR CLUB NOW FOR THIS FREE
EDUCATIONAL BOOKLET AND GET A
FREE MICROSCOPIC HAIR AND SCALP
ANALYSIS AT ANY OF OUR HAIR CLUB
CENTERS NATIONWIDE.
YOUNG OR OLD, MAN OR WOMAN,
NO MATTER WHAT KIND OF HAIR LOSS
YOU MAY HAVE, HAIR CLUB HAS
A UNIQUE SOLUTION FOR YOU,
GUARANTEED.
NO OTHER COMPANY ON THE PLANET
CAN MAKE THAT CLAIM.
HAIR CLUB HAS BEEN THE
RECOGNIZED LEADER IN HAIR LOSS
SOLUTIONS FOR OVER 30 YEARS,
WITH CENTERS IN OVER 90
LOCATIONS AND OVER 50,000
SATISFIED CLIENTS.
CALL NOW AND GET THE FACTS.
HAIR CLUB'S NEW BREAKTHROUGH
EDUCATIONAL BOOKLET IS
YOURS FREE.
THIS VITAL NEW INFORMATION
ENDORSED BY PROMINENT PHYSICIANS
CAN CHANGE YOUR LIFE.
PICK UP THE PHONE RIGHT NOW
AND WE'LL RUSH IT TO YOU FREE
WITH ABSOLUTELY NO OBLIGATION.
AS AN ADDED BONUS, WE'LL ALSO
GIVE YOU A FREE, PRIVATE, AND
CONFIDENTIAL MICROSCOPIC
HAIR AND SCALP ANALYSIS.
THIS IS A $150 VALUE, BUT IT'S
YOURS FREE IF YOU CALL
RIGHT NOW.
THIS OFFER IS FOR A LIMITED
TIME ONLY.
DON'T TOLERATE HAIR LOSS
ANOTHER DAY.
LOOK YOUNGER AND FEEL
MORE CONFIDENT.
TAKE ON THE WORLD LIKE
YOUR OLD SELF.
CALL NOW AND CHANGE
YOUR LIFE FOREVER.
HAIR CLUB-- WE DO IT ALL.
FOR YOU.
[♪...]
>> AT THIS VERY MOMENT, HAIR
CLUB HAS MORE THAN 50,000
CLIENTS NATIONWIDE, 50,000
PEOPLE WHO, LIKE YOU, WANTED
TO DO SOMETHING ABOUT THEIR
HAIR LOSS.
WE'D LIKE YOU TO MEET SOME OF
THOSE CLIENTS NOW AND VIEW SOME
OF THEIR AMAZING RESULTS.
HAIR CLUB HAS CHANGED THEIR
LIVES, AND IT ALL STARTED WITH
ONE SIMPLE PHONE CALL.
>> I'M AN OLD GUY WITH A YOUNG
WIFE AND YOUNG KIDS.
I GOT A FIVE-YEAR-OLD,
I GOT A SEVEN-YEAR-OLD.
THERE'S A LOT OF GUYS
OUT THERE LIKE ME.
I KNOW A LOT OF YOU GUYS WAITED
TILL LATER IN LIFE TO GET
MARRIED AND RAISE YOUR FAMILIES.
IT'S KIND OF IMPORTANT FOR ME
WHEN I DROP MY KIDS OFF THAT THE
OTHER KIDS DON'T THINK I'M THEIR
GRANDFATHER, O.K.?
YOU KNOW, GUYS, WE DON'T SIT
AROUND AND TALK ABOUT FASHION
AND HAIRSTYLES A WHOLE LOT, AND
WHEN I'M SITTING AROUND A POKER
TABLE OR UNDER THE LIGHTS OF A
POOL TABLE, NOBODY GIVES ME
ANY GRIEF.
IT LOOKS GOOD, IT LOOKS NATURAL,
AND THAT'S ALL THAT ANYBODY
CARES ABOUT.
PEOPLE ASK ME ABOUT IT, I'M NOT
AFRAID TO TELL 'EM, "YEAH, MAN,
I DID SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
I GOT MY HAIR CUT."
>> MY SISTER ACTUALLY SAW THE
HAIR CLUB COMMERCIAL, AND SHE
DRAGGED ME OUT OF THE HOUSE
ON A SATURDAY, SAYS, "COME ON,
LET'S GO."
I GET THERE, RIGHT?
I SEE THE INFOMERCIAL.
THEY TALK TO ME ABOUT, YOU KNOW,
WHAT IT WOULD BE LIKE AND WHAT
THEY COULD POSSIBLY DO FOR ME.
AT THAT POINT, I SAYS, "I'M
WILLING TO GIVE IT A CHANCE."
I AM SO GLAD THAT I DID.
IT HAS BEEN THE BEST THING THAT
I HAVE EVER DONE IN TERMS OF
HELPING MY SELF-ESTEEM, RIGHT,
LOOKING LIKE THE WOMAN THAT I
CAN BE, RIGHT, AND I FLAUNT IT
BECAUSE I CAN.
>> I FIRST REALIZED I STARTED
LOSING HAIR ABOUT 21, 22, AND I
WAS LOOKING 32 RATHER QUICKLY,
SO IT ADDED 10, 15 YEARS TO ME
IMMEDIATELY.
YOU'RE A LITTLE EMBARRASSED.
THERE'S NO WAY BEFORE I HAD MY
HAIR I COULD HAVE WALKED UP TO
DEMENA AND ASKED HER TO GO
OUT WITH ME AND BE WHERE WE'RE
AT NOW.
I JUST DIDN'T HAVE THE
CONFIDENCE BEFORE.
WE'VE GOT ABOUT A FEW MONTHS
LEFT UNTIL THE WEDDING, AND
THAT'S ALL SHE THINKS ABOUT,
I KNOW, BUT... 'CAUSE I'M NOT
GONNA LOOK, WELL, 30 YEARS
OLDER.
I'M GONNA LOOK LIKE A YOUNG MAN
MARRYING A BEAUTIFUL WOMAN,
SO IT'S GONNA BE GREAT.
>> WE HAVE A LIBRARY OF
THOUSANDS OF TESTIMONIAL LETTERS
FROM HAPPY CLIENTS.
ALTHOUGH HAIR CLUB MAINTAINS
A HIGH LEVEL OF CONFIDENTIALITY
AND DISCRETION, THESE CLIENTS
WERE SO HAPPY WITH THEIR
RESULTS, THEY WANTED TO SHARE
THEIR EXPERIENCES WITH YOU.
>> WHEN YOU GO INTO THESE
CENTERS, THE STAFF IS SO
WELL-TRAINED AND THEY'RE SO
CARING, BECAUSE THEY TRULY CARE
ABOUT PEOPLE'S LOOKS, AND ONE
THING YOU NEED TO KNOW IS A LOT
OF PEOPLE ARE DOING THIS, MORE
PEOPLE THAN YOU'LL EVER KNOW.
I JUST IMMEDIATELY FELT
REJUVENATED.
I FELT LIKE I HAD A FACE-LIFT,
THE WHOLE NINE YARDS.
IT WAS JUST A WONDERFUL
EXPERIENCE.
>> I STARTED LOSING MY HAIR
WHEN I WAS 28 YEARS OLD, AND I
WAS DEVASTATED.
I SAW THE COMMERCIALS.
I HAD TO ORDER THE BROCHURE.
THE MEN ON THE COMMERCIAL LOOKED
SO NATURAL, SO REAL.
I WENT INTO THE CENTER.
IT CHANGED MY LIFE.
I'M TELLING YOU, MEN, I FELT
SO GOOD ABOUT MYSELF.
I'VE NEVER FELT BETTER.
>> BEFORE I WENT TO HAIR CLUB,
MY HAIR WAS LIMP AND LIFELESS
AND THERE WAS SO LITTLE THAT I
COULD DO WITH IT.
I REMEMBER TRAVELING OUTSIDE ON
SUMMER DAYS, HAVING TO WEAR A
HAT BECAUSE MY HEAD WOULD COME
HOME AND I WOULD BE SUNBURNED.
I WOULD GET HOME AND IT WOULD
BE SUNBURNED.
NOW I DON'T HAVE THAT PROBLEM.
I CAN HAVE NOTHING ON MY HEAD,
AND I CAN RIDE AROUND IN A
CONVERTIBLE WITH MY HAIR
FLIPPING AROUND, AND IT
FEELS GREAT.
>> AS A HIGH DIVER, I'VE BEEN
EVERYWHERE, AND I DIVE IN FRONT
OF THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE EVERY
DAY, AND I WALK RIGHT UP CLOSE
TO EVERY ONE OF THESE PEOPLE
AFTER THE SHOWS, AND NOBODY
CAN TELL THE DIFFERENCE.
IT FEELS GREAT.
I MEAN, THE CONFIDENCE THAT I
HAVE WHEN I WALK UP TO 'EM IS
GREAT, AND IT GIVES ME THE
CONFIDENCE WHEN I'M STANDING UP
ON THE LADDER TO KNOW THAT I
LOOK GOOD AND I LOOK GOOD FROM
ALL ANGLES, AND THAT'S BEEN JUST
A GREAT EXPERIENCE FOR ME.
>> CRITERIA WAS VERY SIMPLE.
IF IT WAS DETECTABLE, I WAS OUT.
>> WITH THE LINE OF WORK THAT
I'M IN-- I'M IN SALES-- MY IMAGE
IS EVERYTHING, SO THE BETTER I
LOOK, THE MORE I SELL, BECAUSE
THEY'RE BUYING A PART OF ME.
SO MY APPEARANCE IS VERY
IMPORTANT TO ME.
AND I KNOW THAT REGARDLESS IF
I'M AT THE GYM OR WITH MY MAN,
MY HAIR IS LOOKING FANTASTIC.
>> AS YOU'VE JUST SEEN, HAIR
CLUB REALLY LISTENS TO ITS
CLIENTS AND REALLY CARES ABOUT
IMPROVING PEOPLE'S LIVES.
WHEN WE COME BACK, YOU'LL SEE
WHAT PROVEN SOLUTION IS BEST FOR
YOU BASED ON YOUR AGE, LEVEL OF
HAIR LOSS, AND EXPECTATIONS.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
>> Announcer: DON'T TOLERATE
ANOTHER DAY OF HAIR LOSS OR
THINNING HAIR.
BECAUSE NOW THE SOLUTION YOU
NEED TO GET A FULLER, NATURAL
HEAD OF HAIR IS JUST ONE
PHONE CALL AWAY.
HAIR CLUB IS THE ONLY COMPANY
IN THE WORLD TO OFFER ALL TESTED
AND PROVEN HAIR LOSS SOLUTIONS,
BECAUSE NO SINGLE SOLUTION
IS RIGHT FOR EVERY TYPE
OF HAIR LOSS.
CALL HAIR CLUB NOW FOR THIS FREE
EDUCATIONAL BOOKLET AND GET A
FREE MICROSCOPIC HAIR AND SCALP
ANALYSIS AT ANY OF OUR HAIR CLUB
CENTERS NATIONWIDE.
YOUNG OR OLD, MAN OR WOMAN,
NO MATTER WHAT KIND OF HAIR LOSS
YOU MAY HAVE, HAIR CLUB HAS
A UNIQUE SOLUTION FOR YOU,
GUARANTEED.
NO OTHER COMPANY ON THE PLANET
CAN MAKE THAT CLAIM.
HAIR CLUB HAS BEEN THE
RECOGNIZED LEADER IN HAIR LOSS
SOLUTIONS FOR OVER 30 YEARS,
WITH CENTERS IN OVER 90
LOCATIONS AND OVER 50,000
SATISFIED CLIENTS.
CALL NOW AND GET THE FACTS.
HAIR CLUB'S NEW BREAKTHROUGH
EDUCATIONAL BOOKLET IS
YOURS FREE.
THIS VITAL NEW INFORMATION
ENDORSED BY PROMINENT PHYSICIANS
CAN CHANGE YOUR LIFE.
PICK UP THE PHONE RIGHT NOW
AND WE'LL RUSH IT TO YOU FREE
WITH ABSOLUTELY NO OBLIGATION.
AS AN ADDED BONUS, WE'LL ALSO
GIVE YOU A FREE, PRIVATE, AND
CONFIDENTIAL MICROSCOPIC
HAIR AND SCALP ANALYSIS.
THIS IS A $150 VALUE, BUT IT'S
YOURS FREE IF YOU CALL
RIGHT NOW.
THIS OFFER IS FOR A LIMITED
TIME ONLY.
DON'T TOLERATE HAIR LOSS
ANOTHER DAY.
LOOK YOUNGER AND FEEL
MORE CONFIDENT.
TAKE ON THE WORLD LIKE
YOUR OLD SELF.
CALL NOW AND CHANGE
YOUR LIFE FOREVER.
HAIR CLUB-- WE DO IT ALL.
FOR YOU.
[♪...]
>> SINCE 1976, HAIR CLUB HAS
BEEN DELIVERING SOLUTIONS
THAT ACTUALLY WORK.
THE PROOF IS IN THE PICTURES.
VISIT HAIR CLUB TODAY AND GET
STARTED ON A CUSTOMIZED SOLUTION
THAT WILL WORK FOR YOU.
YOU'VE SEEN A NUMBER OF CLIENTS
TODAY WHO HAVE IMPROVED THEIR
APPEARANCE BY TAKING THAT FIRST
STEP AND CALLING HAIR CLUB.
IMAGINE WHAT WE CAN DO FOR YOU.
WHETHER YOU WANT A FULL HEAD OF
HAIR OR YOU'RE JUST TRYING TO
KEEP WHAT YOU HAVE, HAIR CLUB
HAS AN OPTION THAT'S RIGHT
FOR YOU.
SO GET READY TO LOOK GREAT AND
FEEL BETTER THAN YOU'VE EVER
FELT BEFORE.
HAIR CLUB HAS MORE THAN 50,000
CLIENTS IN NORTH AMERICA.
THAT'S MORE THAN 50,000 REASONS
TO CALL, BUT THE MOST IMPORTANT
REASON IS YOU.
WHETHER YOU'RE 25 OR 65, YOU'LL
BE AMAZED AT WHAT HAIR CLUB
CAN DO FOR YOU.
CALL NOW.
STOPPING YOUR HAIR LOSS
IS JUST A PHONE CALL AWAY.
>> AND I CAN DO WHATEVER
I WANT EVERY DAY.
I CAN GO SWIMMING.
I CAN PLAY SPORTS.
I CAN DO WHATEVER.
IT'S FABULOUS.
>> THAT ONE DAY THAT I MADE THAT
PHONE CALL WAS THE BEST DECISION
I MADE, SO IF THERE'S ANY ADVICE
THAT I CAN GIVE, MAKE THAT CALL.
>> [CHUCKLES] YOU GUYS DON'T
NEED TO SHAVE THAT HEAD.
YOU KNOW, KEEP SOME HAIR
ON THERE.
JOIN THE HAIR CLUB LIKE I DID.
>> I CALLED HAIR CLUB, AND I
HAVE NEVER FELT BETTER.
I'VE GOT GREAT, HEALTHY HAIR,
I LOOK YOUNGER, AND I FEEL
TERRIFIC.
>> DON'T HESITATE.
GO IN RIGHT NOW, BECAUSE YOU
WILL FEEL BETTER, YOU'LL LOOK
BETTER, AND IT'LL BE SOMETHING
THAT YOU WILL APPRECIATE
IN THE LONG RUN.
>> IT'S ALL ABOUT YOU.
HAIR CLUB DOES WHAT'S RIGHT
FOR YOU.
>> I LOVE MY HAIR.
I LOVE HOW I FEEL ABOUT MY HAIR.
>> SO I WENT AND CHECKED IT OUT,
MADE THE PHONE CALL, AND IT
REALLY CHANGED MY LIFE.
>> AND IF YOU WANT TO LOOK
BETTER, IF YOU WANT TO FEEL
BETTER ABOUT YOURSELF,
HAIR CLUB IS THE WAY TO GO.
>> EVERY DAY THAT I GET UP,
I CAN SAY "OOH," RIGHT?
"THIS IS ME. THIS IS WHO I AM.
I LOOK GREAT TODAY."
THANK YOU, HAIR CLUB.
YOU HAVE MADE SUCH A DIFFERENCE
IN MY LIFE.
[♪...]
CALL THE NUMBER ON YOUR SCREEN.
>> Woman: ♪ OOH... YEAH
♪ YEAH, YEAH, YEAH
[♪...]
>> Announcer: HAIR CLUB--
WE DO IT ALL. FOR YOU.
[♪...]
THE PRECEDING WAS PAID FOR AND
FURNISHED BY HAIR CLUB FOR MEN
AND WOMEN.
THIS STATION IS NOT RESPONSIBLE
FOR CLAIMS MADE IN THE PRECEDING
PROGRAM.
[♪...]
>> THE FOLLOWING IS
A PAID PRESENTATION
FOR SUPERSMILE
BROUGHT TO YOU BY
GUTHY-RENKER.
NONE OF THE TESTIMONIALS
OR DENTISTS IN THIS SHOW
HAVE BEEN PAID
TO SHARE THEIR OPINIONS.
>> A BRIGHT AND HEALTHY SMILE
CAN BE YOUR
BIGGEST BEAUTY ASSET.
IT'S ONE OF THE FIRST THINGS
PEOPLE NOTICE ABOUT YOU,
BUT IF YOU'RE EMBARRASSED
BY YOUR SMILE BECAUSE OF YOUR
STAINED, DISCOLORED, DULL TEETH
IT'S HARD TO FEEL GOOD
ABOUT YOURSELF.
NOW, YOU CAN TURN BACK
THE CLOCK ON YOUR TEETH
AND SAFELY GET A NATURALLY
WHITER, BRIGHTER, SEXIER SMILE
THANKS TO AN ASTONISHING
NEW TEETH WHITENING SYSTEM.
IT'S TIME TO TURN YOUR SMILE
INTO A SUPERSMILE.
>> MY SMILE A MONTH AGO
WAS MORE LIKE THIS.