[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Jimmy: DAN DEACON, HIS ALBUM
IS CALLED "AMERICA", IT IS OUT
NOW.
I WANT TO THANK DAN, CARSON
DALY, ZACHARY KNIGHTON, AND I
WANT TO APOLOGIZE TO MATT DAMON.
WE RAN OUT OF TIME FOR HIM.
HE WILL BE RESCHEDULED.
THANK YOU FOR WATCHING AND GOOD
NIGHT.
>> SKY 7 HD OVER EAST BAY PLANT
WHERE A MASSIVE FAIR GUTTED THE
BUILDING AND FORCED PEOPLE TO
GET OUT FAST.  GOOD EVENING.
>> WE ARE NOW LEARNING WHAT WAS
HAPPENING AT THE TIME THIS FIR
BROKE OUT.  THOSE FLAMES
QUICKLY ENGULFED CNH ENTERPRISE
AT PWOING AVENUE NOT FAR FROM
INTERSTATE 6 80.  AMMA IS AT
THE SCENE FOR US LIVE TONIGHT
WITH THE LATEST.
>>Reporter:  IT REALLY IS
FORTUNATE THAT NOBODY WAS
INJURED IN THIS FIRE.  CNH
ENTERPRISE KNOWN FOR PRECISION
MACHINING, WE WILL GO
FABRICATING THAT MEANS THAT
INSIDE THIS BUILDING HERE THEY
HAD THINGS LEAK COMBUSTIBLE OI
OIL, FLAMMABLE GAS, METAL
SHAVINGS ALL BURNING.  THERE IS
A MACHINE SHOP AS WELL AS SOME
OFFICES ONE OF THE EMPLOYEE
TOLDS ME THAT HE BELIEVES THE
FIR BEGAN NEAR ONE OF THE
MACHINES.  WITH YOU BUILDING IS
SO BADLY BURNED NOBODY HAS BEEN
LET INSIDE SO INVESTIGATORS
STILL DON'T KNOW EXACTLY WHAT
CAUSED THE FIRE CNH ENTERPRISE
IN FREE MONT A MERE SHELL OF
WHETHER IT WAS HOURS AGO.
FIREFIGHTERS DON'T YET KNOW
WHAT SPARKED THE INTENSELY HOT
FIRE THAT TORE THROUGH THE
BUILDING INTERIOR EARLY IN THE
AFTERNOON.  SKY 7 HD CONSPIRE
TOURED THE BILLOWING BLACK
SMOKE THAT COULD BE SEEN FOR
MILES.
>> IT WAS FULLY INVOLVED WHEN
WE ARRIVED.
>>Reporter:  THERE WERE
APPROXIMATELY 60 MYE INS THE
BUILDING WHEN THE FAIR BROKE
OUT.  ALL MANAGEED TO ESCAPE
UNHARMED, N TRIEDONE MAN TRIED T
OUT THE FIRE.
>> SEVERAL BUSINESS HOUSE NEXT
CURE INCLUDING A PAINTING
COMPANY WERE EVACUATED AS
PRECAUTION.  THE BUILDING
SPARED.
>> FIRE WALL HELD WELL AND
DESIGNED WHAT IT WAS TO DO
SIGNIFICANT LOSS ON ONE SIDE OF
THE WALL AND READY TO GOOD ON
THE OTHER SIDE.
>>Reporter:  DNH MAKE COMPONENT
OF ALUMINUM USED IN
SEMICONDUCTOR INDUSTRY.
INITIALLY CONCERN ABOUT
HAZARDOUS MATERIALS BURNING SO
NEARBY BUSINESSES WERE TOLD TO
SHELTER IN PLACE WHILE AIR
QUALITY IF OR ASSESSED THE
RISK. IT WAS DERL THE FAIR WAS
NO MORE DANGEROUS THAN REGULAR
HOUSE FIRE.
>> NOTHING LEFT.  JUST
INCREDIBLE HOW FAST IT WENT.
>>Reporter:  STEVE IS DIRECTOR
OF OPERATION AND SAYS THE
COMPANY HAS VERY GOOD INSURANC
INSURANCE.
>> THE EMPLOYEE WILL BE COVERED
AS FAR AS LOSS OF SALARY AND
WAGES.
>>Reporter:  ORIGINAL BUILDING
WAS BURNED SO BA'ATH BADLY
FIREFIGHTERS WERE UNABLE TO GO
INSIDE.
>> RAV FELL THROUGH EARLY IN
THE FIRE AND UNSAFE UNTIL WE
HAVE DAY LATE AGAIN AND WE HAVE
BUILDING CONSTRUCTION ENGINEERS
COME DOWN AND KUHAN OF
STABILIZE IT FOR US.  ONE OF
THE FARES TOLD ME THAT THERE
WAS NO SPRINKLER SYSTEM INSIDE
THE BUILDING AND BATTALION
CHIEF TELLS ME THAT WOULD HAVE
HELPED A LOT BUT THE OLDER
BUILDINGS JUST DON'T HAVE THE
SYSTEMS IN PLACE YET.  NEW CNH
PLANS TO MEET WITH THE EMPLOYE
EMPLOYEES TO TALK ABOUT WHAT IS
NEXT.  THEY HOPE TO GET A
TEMPORARY LOCATION TO GET
BUSINESS BACK UP AND RUNNING.
THIS IS 7 NEWS.
>> OKAY THANKS SO MUCH.
>> WE HAVE A FROSTY NIGHT AHEA
AHEAD.  LET'S CHECK IN NOW WITH
SANDHYA WITH THE LOOK AT CHILL
AND RADAR TONIGHT.
>> LOOKING AT ICE COLD NIGHT
AGAIN AS A MATTER OF FACT WE
HAVE FROST ADVISORY GOING UP
SHORTLY.  YOU WILL SEE THE
CLOUDS HIGH LEVEL CLOUDS
APPROACHING UKIAH BUT NOT QUITE
THERE TO TEMPERATURE FALLING AN
FALLING FAST LACK AT THE
NUMBERS.  34 DEGREES 34 IN
SANTA ROSA 2 DEGREES SHY OF
FREEZING.  35 IN NAP A.36
DEGREES IN FAIRFIELD.
TEMPERATURES EXPECTED TO DROP
MORE EAST BAY INTERIOR VALLEY
NORTHERN SALINAS VALLEY UNDER
FROST ADVISORY 2:00 A.M.  TO
8:00 P.M.  H1N1 A&M.  WATCH OUT
FOR SIDEWALKS SLIPPERY AND IF
THE CHILL WASN'T ENOUGH YOU
WILL NEED TO BUNCH YOU UP WHEN
YOU HEAD OUT THE DOOR IN THE
MORNING.  WHEN YOU NEED THE
UMBRELLA I'LL LET YOU KNOW.
SOME SYSTEMS ARE HEADED YOUR
WAY.
>> SEE YOU SOON.
>> DEVELOPING NEWS.  WOMAN IS
RECOVERING TONIGHT AFTER
FALLING INTO THE BAY OFF THE
EMBARCADERO IN SAN FRANCISCO.
IT HAPPENED BETWEEN THE
WATERFRONT RESTAURANT AND THE
FERRY BUILDING.  SHE WAS
RESCUED QUICKLY BY FAIR CREW.
THE CHIEF TELLS US SHE APPEARED
INTOXICATED.  SHE HAS BEEN
TAKEN TO HOSPITAL AS PRECAUTIO
PRECAUTION.
>> SOME BART STATION HOT SPOTS
FOR CRIMINALS ESPECIALLY DURING
THE HOLIDAY SEASON.  ALLEN
REPORTS NOW FROM THE WEST HE
CAN LAND PART STATION WHERE
ARMED ESCORTS ARE WALKING
PASSENGERS TO THE CARS TONIGHT.
>> INCENSE MAN SEE AS LOT AT
THE WEST OAKLAND BART STATION
SELLING HIS GOODS.
>> PATIENT JUST WALKED OFF
THOUGHT SHE WAS SAFE AND GOING
TO HER CAR AND GUY RAN BY
GRABBED HER STUFF AND TOOK OFF
RUNNING.
>>Reporter:  MORE OF THE CRIMES
HAPPEN AROUND THE HOLIDAY.
ESPECIALLY WITH BART PASSENGERS
RETURNING HOME AFTER DAY OF
SHOPPING TONIGHT BART AND
OAKLAND POLICE PRIVATE SECURITY
GUARDS AND SENTENCE VOLUNTEERS
ARE OFFERING FREE NIGHTTIME
ESCORTS FOR PASSENGERS WALKING
TO THEIR CARS.  MICHELLE TOOK
ADVANTAGE OF IT.
>> HOLIDAY SEASON SO PEOPLE ARE
REALLY AMPED UP TRYING TO GET
READY FOR THE HOTEL DIFFICULT
AND DO ANY WAY THEY CAN.  SO
BETTER TO BE SAFE THAN SORRY,
THE LARGE SCALE PROGRAM IS JUST
FOR ONE NIGHT.  BART SAYS IT
PROVIDES ASSISTANCE YEAR-ROUND.
>> ANY TIME BART CUSTOMER WOULD
LICK AN ESCORT TO THE CAR ALL
THEY HAVE TO DIES ASK THE
STATION AGENT OR THEY CAN
TELEPHONE BART POLICE.
>> MAIN PURPOSE OF THIS PROGRAM
IS TO TEACH PASSENGERS NOT TO
LOOK LIKE EASY PRAY.
>> DON'T DISPRABINGT WALKING
AND TALKING ON THE PHONE OR
LISTENING TO MUSIC.  DON'T WEAR
NASHY JEWELRY.  MAKE EYE
CONTACT WITH PEOPLE AND BE
AWARE OF YOUR SURROUNDINGS IN A
NUTSHELL THEY ARE TRYING TO GET
MORE PEOPLE TO BE STREET SMART.
THIS IS ABC 7 NEWS.
>> NEW AT 11.  36 HOUR CRIME
SPRAE TARGETING PHARMACY HAVE
PLEASANTON AND DUBLIN POLICE
LACKING FOR TEAM OF CROOK THEY
BELIEVE IS WORKING TOGETHER.
THIS MAP SHOWS THE FORE STORES
THE MEN TARGETED TODAY AND LAST
NIGHT.  THE ROBBER HANDED OVER
A SIMILAR NOTE DEMANING
PRESCRIPTION DRUGS AND CLAIMING
TO BE ARMED.
>> MASSIVE CYBERATTACK IS
EXPECTED TO BE UNLEASHED IN THE
COMING MONTHS AND THE TASHINGT
COULD BE YOUR BANK ACCOUNT.
PLAN APPARENTLY INVOLVES DOZENS
OF BANKS.  LIL YAP IS HERE WITH
WHAT WE KNOW ABOUT THIS AND HOW
TO PROTECT YOUR MONEY.
>> REPORTS OF CIRCULATING SINCE
OCTOBER THAT THE PARTICULAR
CYBERATTACK IN THE PLANNING
STAGES.  WELL TODAY MCFEE
CORROBORATED THE REPORTS AND
THE ATTACK IS PLANNED FORTH
SPRING.  I WE WEREN'T TINY FORM
CONSUMERS THE ATTACK IS CO-BE
AWARE.
>>Reporter:  THEY HAVE BEEN
INVESTIGATING FOR MOST AND
COMPUTER SECURITY COMPANY SAYS
THE EVIDENCE IS CLEAR.  HACKERS
PLANNING TO ATTACK THE BANK
ACCOUNT.  MCFEE SO FAR DETECTED
HUNDREDS OF COMPUTERS INFECTED
WITH A VIRUS MASTER MINDED BY
SOMEBODY IN RUSSIAN 8.  WHEN
YOU TRY TO LOG IN A FINANCIAL
INSTITUTION THAT'S WHEN THE
VIRUS AMITY VAITS AND REPLICATE
INDICATE OR CLONE YOUR P C MANY
TO A SERVER IN RUSSIA AND ONCE
THEY CLONE THEY TRY TO USE IN
THE BANK.
>>Reporter:  THEY FUNNEL MONEY
FROM BANK ACCOUNTS INCLUDING
WELLS FARGO CITY BANK AND CHAS
CHASE.  THE HOPE IS THAT THE
FINANCIAL INDUSTRY WAY OF
DEALING WITH CYBERTHIEF OVER
THE YEARS WILL MINIMIZE LOSS.
A MANAGEMENT COMPANY SAYS THIS.
>> UTILITY COMPANY THAT DEAL IN
IT.  THEY HAVE THE RESOURCE
ALSO.  HAVE TO KEEL WITH THESE
SORT OF ISSUES BUT IT'S THE
COST OF DOING BI-HE SAYS THE
PLAN INVOLVES TARGETING PEOPLE
OF HIGH NET WORTH BUT ALL
CUSTOMERS ARE ADVISED TO MAKE
SURE THE ANTI-VIRUS SURF WEAR
IS WORKING THE WAY IT SHOULD.
>> POTENTIAL FOR ATTACK.  WE
THINK THE LAKELY HOOD IS HIGH.
WHY WON'T YOU.
>>Reporter:  MCFEE IS
COORDINATING WITH LAW
ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS AND
WORKING WITH SEVERAL BANK TO
PREPARE THEM FOR THE POTENTIAL
ATTACK.
>> LILLIAN REPORTING.
>> REMAINS OF MEXICAN AMERICANS
SUPERSTAR JENNI RIVERA IS NOW
AT A MORTUARY IN LONG BEACH.
HER FAMILY IDENTIFIED THE
REMAINS EARLIER TODAY AND WENT
AHEAD WITH CREMATION WITHOUT
WAITING FOR DNA RESULTS.  SHE
AND 6 WRORS KILLED SUNDAY WHEN
THEY ARE LEARJET CRASHED IN
MEXICO.
>>> STUDENTS AT 2 BY AREA
SCHOOLS WILL SEE EXTRA SECURITY
TOMORROW.  SHERIFF'S DEPUTY
WILL BE ON CAMPUS AT THESE 2
SCHOOLS AFTER BOMB THREAT
FORCED THE CLOSURE OF BOTH
SCHOOLS TODAY.  GRAFFITI
SCROLLED ON WALL AT LYNN BROOK
HIGH IN SAN JOSE CLAIM THERE
WAS A BOMB AT MONT VISTA AND
THREATENED TO KILL A TEACHER.
NO DID HE ADVICE FOUND.  AND
THEY ARE MAKING SURE THE
TEACHER NAMED IN THE THREAT IS
PROTECTED.
>> UP NEXT.  SEX DRUG SCANDAL,
REHAB AND RECONCILIATION AND
TROUBLED EX LOVER DISTURBING
TEXT TO THE ABC 7 NEWS I TEAM.
>> AND SPOON FEEDING SUGAR TO
THE NATION.  MEGA STARS COMING
UNDER FIRE TONIGHT.
>> THEN LATER ON "NIGHTLINE".
>> COME UP NEXT ON NIGHTLINE
WITH A BOMB SHELL STORAGE WAR
CUSHION.  WE ASK HOW REAL YOUR
FAITH REALITY TV SHOW ARE THESE
DAYS.  MY INTERVIEW WITH THE
ROLLING STONES ON THE ONCE IN A
LIFE TIME TOUR CELEBRATING 50
YEARS OF SEX DRUG
[ Female Announcer ]
CAN YOUR PANCAKE MIX DO THIS?
SURE, BISQUICK MAKES
DELICIOUS PANCAKES,
BUT THAT'S JUST THE START.
UNLEASH THE HIDDEN POWER
OF BISQUICK.
SEE WHAT YOU CAN MAKE
AT BISQUICK.COM.
[ Female Announcer ] LET
BETTY CROCKER DO THE MEASURING
AND GET A HEAD START
ON DELICIOUS HOMEMADE COOKIES.
♪
JUST POUR, MIX...LOVE.
ñ
>> WELL ONE OF THE BAY AREA BI
BIGGEST POLITICAL SCANDAL OF
THE YEAR TOOK A MAJOR TURN
TODAY.  NADIA FORMER ALAMEDA
COUNTY SUPERVISOR AND WIFE OF
STATE TREASURER BILL DROPPED
HER REQUEST FOR RESTRAINING
ORDER AGAINST HER FORMER
BOYFRIEND.  DAN HAS THE
EXCLUSIVE I TEAM INVESTIGATION.
>> HER ATTORNEY ASKED THE JUDGE
TO DELAY HEARING NADIA REQUEST
FOR RESTRAINING ORDER AGAINST
FORMER BOYFRIEND STEVE JACK
UNTIL SHE GETS OUT OF REHAB IN
FEBRUARY.  THE SCANDAL BLEW UP
10 MONTHS AGO AFTER A VIOLENT
CONFRONTATION BETWEEN L THEM
THAT THE NEWARK MOTEL.  IT LEFT
HER WITH SCRAPES AND DEEP
BRUISES.  BUT AUTHORITIES
DECLINED TO PRESS CHARGES.
AFTER THEY PUBLICLY DISCUSSED
THE METH USE AND SEX TAPE THEY
MADE SHE RESIGNED FROM THE
ALAMEDA COUNTY BOARD OF
SUPERVISOR AND ENTERED REHAB.
THE JUDGE SUGGESTED DROPPING
THE ISSUE OF RESTRAINING ORDER
FOR NOW AND RESCHEDULING IF
NECESSARY WHEN NADIA RETURNS TO
THE BAY AREA.
>> COURT WOULD TAKE IT OFF
CALENDAR AND REISSUE WE'LL DO
THAT.  OKAY GOOD ENOUGH THANK
YOU.
>>Reporter:  WHAT DO YOU THINK
THE ODDS ARE OF YOU COME BANG.
DO YOU THINK THIS COULD DIE
RIGHT HERE.
>> I THINK THERE'S A GOOD
CHANCE THIS MAY DIE HERE.
NADIA WILL GO THROUGH TREATMEN
TREATMENT.  RECONSIDER HER
OPTIONS AND ONE OF THE OPTIONS
WILL BE OF COURSE TO CONTINUE
TO PURSUE THIS ANOTHER OPTION
MAY TO LET MATTERS LIE THE WAY
THEY ARE AND MAV ON WITH THEIR
LIFE.
>>Reporter:  HER HUSBAND BILL
FILED FOR DIVORCE IN JULY.  BUT
THAT'S NOW ON HOLD.  THAT BILL
AND NADIA ARE WORKING WELL
TOGETHER.  HE'S PAYING FOR
REHAB AND BRINGING THEIR SON TO
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA REGULARLY
TO VISIT NADIA IT'S A MUCH
DIFFERENT STORY FOR STEVE CHIC
CHICK.  THERE'S A WARRANT FOR
HIS ARREST AFTER HE MISSED
COURT APPEARANCE.  POLICE SAY
HE TRIED TO STEAL A SWEATSHIRT
FROM MACY WHILE HIGH ON METH IN
AUGUST.  I TEXTED HIM BEFORE
THE HEARING TODAY ASKING IF HE
WOULD ATTEND.  HE ANSWERED NOT
FEELING LIKE GOING TO JAIL AND
THEY WOULD TAKE ME IF I SHOWED.
I CAN'T GET PAST THIS
CONNECTION HER AND I HAD WAS SO
STRONG.  LAST NIGHT I SLEPT ON
THE STREETS AGAIN.  I LOST
EVERYTHING BECAUSE OF HER AND
THE LIFE SHE FORCED ME INTO.  I
TRIED TO CALL HIM SEVERAL TAKE
PLACE SEE IF HE'S OKAY BUT GOT
HIS VOICE MAIL.  THESE ARE
STREAMS OF HIS TECH ON OUR
WELCOME BACK SITE.  NADIA IS
STILL FACING TRUCK AND CHILD
ENDANGERMENT CHARGES IN
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA BUT HER
LAWYER SAYS THE CASE MAY
DROPPED IF SHE DOES WELL IF
REHAB.  FOR THE I TEAM, ABC 7
NEWS.
>>> WELL OF L WE HONOR THE
RESIP YAEPT OF 2012 PROFILE OF
EXCELLENCE AWARDS TONIGHT.  24
YEARS PROPERTY FILE OF
EXCELLENT SERIES CELEBRATED THE
BAY AREA DIVERSITY.  EACH 15
PEOPLE HONORED HAVE MADE
IMPORTANT CONTRIBUTIONS TO OUR
COMMUNICATE.  YOU ARE INVITED
VIEW RECENT EPISODE OF PROFILE
OF EXCELLENCE AT OUR WEB SITE.
AMAZING PEOPLE DOING AMAZING
THINGS.
>> CONGRATULATIONSS TO ALL OF
THEM.
>> WE WANT TO THANK YOU FOR
MAKING ABC 7 SHARE YOUR HOLIDAY
FOOD DRIVE.  W SUCCESS.  WE
BROADCAST FROM SEVERAL
LOCATIONS AROUND THE BAY AREA
YESTERDAY ASKING TO YOU DONATE
FOOD MONEY FOR BAY AREA FOOD
BANK.  THERE'S MICHAEL IN
ACTION IN WALNUT CREEK.  ALL
TOGETHER YOU DO NATURALLYED
MORE THAN 22,000 DOLLARS TO THE
BAY AREA FOOD BANK JUST
YESTERDAY.  THAT TRANSLATION IS
FOOD FOR 70,000 PEOPLE.  SHARE
YOUR HOTEL DIFFICULT FOOD DRIVE
CONTINUES THROUGH DECEMBER 31.
BY CALLINGATE DO ALLING
THIS NUMBER ON THE SCREEN.  YOU
CAN ALSO GET 10 DOLLARS TEXTING
FEED TO THIS NUMBER ON THE
SCREEN.
>>> THAT IS SUCH DIFFERENCE.
SO MANY PEOPLE STILL IN NEED
THIS TIME OF YEAR.  WEATHER
FORECAST RAIN IS COMING AND YOU
ALREADY KNOW IT'S COLD.
>> REALLY COLD.  SANDY IS HERE
WITH THE FORECAST.
>> COLD FROSTY TONIGHT AS WE
LOOK AT THIS.  HIGH CLOUDS
APPROACHING.  RADAR ON MOUNT
SAINT HELENA TRACK AGO FEW
DROPS AS WE HEAD INTO TOMORROW
MORNING.  RIGHT NOW YOU CAN SEE
THE CHILL IN THE AIR.  33 IN
NAP A.CLOSE TO FREEZING ALREADY
IN FAIRFIELD.  34.  35 IN SANTA
ROSA.  I JUST UPDATED THESE SO
I THOUGHT WOULD I SHAWR THEM
WITH YOU.  ANOTHER FROSTY
MORNING INLAND.  CHANCE OF
LIGHT RAPE TOMORROW.  MORE RAIN
IN THE FORECAST FOR THE WEEKEND
BUT DON'T CANCEL YOUR PLANS.
NOT GOING TO BE THAT BAD.
MORNING LOW DOWN TOLY THE SANTA
ROSA.  32 NAPA LIVERMORE.  AROU
CLOSE TO THAT 35.  33 IN CON
COR.  38 FOR PALO ALTO.  39 SAN
MATEO O.  MAKE SURE YOU HAVE AT
LEAST A COAT OR JACKET EVEN
GLOVES WOULD COME IN HANDY AND
KIDS HAVE THE JACK THAET WOULD
BE GOOD.  HERE'S THE NEXT
FRONT.  BRING US A CHANCE OF
LIGHT RAIN FOR YOUR FRIDAY.
BUT AS WE LOOK AT COMPUTER
ANIMATION IN A MOMENT YOU WILL
SEE WHAT WILL HAPPEN.  SERIES
OF STORMS ARE SETTING UP OVER
THE PACIFIC OVER THE NEXT 7
DAYS BUT THIS REALLY DOESN'T
MEAN A COMPLETE WASH-OUT OVER
THE NEXT 7 DAYS.  COMPUTER
ANIMATION TOMORROW MORNING.
5:00 A.M.  CLOUDS AROUND AS WE
HEAD INTO ABOUT 9:00 A.M.  FEW
SHOWERS MAY SKIRT THE COAST
AROUND SAN MATEO SANTA CRUZ NEW
HAMPSHIRE "NEWSNIGHT"TAME SAN
JOSE TO SANTA CRUZ.  COULD SEE
FEW SHOWERS BEST CHANCE IS IN
THOSE AREAS REALLY FOR THE REST
OF YOU MIX OF SUN AND CLOUDS.
SATURDAY LOOKING FINE UNTIL THE
LATE MORNING HOURS.  10:00 A.M.
START TO SEE RAIN DEVELOPING.
MOST SATURDAY AFTERNOON EVENING
LIGHT MODERATE RAPE.  COULD SEE
SNOW MIXING IN LAKE COUNTY NEAR
UKIAH AREA.  SHOWERS.  REST OF
THE SUNDAY ACTUALLY LOOKING
JUST FINE.  LIGHT SHOWERS FOR
YOUR SUNDAY.  TOMORROW CHANCE
OF FEW SHOWERS.  CARRY UMBRELLA
ON THE SAFE SIDE.  KOTD OR
JAEINGT.  WILL REMAIN CHILLY.
SUNNY BREAK OUT THERE AS WELL
AND AROUND THE BAY.
TEMPERATURES REMAIN LLY.
LET'S CHECK OUT ACCU-WEATHER 7
DAY FOREGO.  CHANCE OF LIGHT
WRITTEN TOMORROW.  SEE SKIES
OUT THERE AS WELL.  RAIN ON
SACHLTS WETTER OF THE TWO DAYS
FOR THE WEEKEND.  UNSETTLED
MONDAY AND THEN YOU LOOK THERE.
IT'S WET AND BREEZY ON
TUESDAY.  MILDER STORM
WEDNESDAY A BREAK AND THEN MORE
RAIN IN THE MIX THURSDAY FOR
REALLY THE ENTIRE DAY AS OF
RATE NOW THE STORM LATEST
COMPUTER MODEL, DON'T LOOK
TERRIBLY IMPRESSIVE NOW FOR THE
MOYVLINGTS NEXT WEEK.
>> OKAY.
>> WE LICK THAT.
>> WE HAVE GIANTS NEWS.
>> YES.  LARRY HERE WITH ALL
THAT.
>> THE GIANTS THEY HAVE A WAY
OF GOING ABOUT THINGS.  NOT
SPLURGING BUT BRINGING BACK ONE
OF THE BLAST TO THE PAST.
TORREZ WILL RETURN.  QUESTION
IS AT WHAT POSITION?
SPORTS COMING UP
INTO GOOD EVENING.  DODGERS
ZOOM PAST THE 200 MILLION
DOLLAR PAYROLL THE GIANTS ARE
STICKING TO THE PLAN.  STICKING
TO THE BUDGET.  A LITTLE HERE A
LITTLE THERE.  BRINGING BACK
FAN FAVORITE TORREZ OUTFIELDER
ONE YEAR DEL FOR TWO MILLION
DOLLARS.  HE WAS KEY
CONTRIBUTOR ON THE 2010 WORLD
SERIES TEAM.  HE WAS DEALT TO
THE METS IN THE ANGEL DEAL AND
NOW COMING BACK.  TORREZ COULD
END UP STARTING IN LEFT FIELD.
SEEING THE DODGERS SPLURGE
ANGEL HAVE TO SPEND TO COMPETE
IN THE L.A.  MAT.  THEY HAVE
JOSH HAMILTON 5 YEARS 1 25
MILLION DOLLARS.  HAMILTON 43
HOMEERS LAST SEASON FOR TEXAS.
HAMILTON POOL HOSE, TROUINGT
ALL IN THE SAME LINE UP FOR THE
ANGELS.  NIGHTMARE FOR OPPOSING
PITCHERS.  LAST TEAM TO BEAT
THE WAR YRS ORLANDO.  10 DAYS
AGO.  SAME MAGIC TEAM THAT THE
WARRIORS FACE TOMORROW NIGHT IN
FLORIDA.  GELLEDEN STATE ON
FIRE LATELY.  BEAT THE NBA
CHAMPION HEAT LAST TONIGHT FOR
THE FIFTH CONSECUTIVE WIN.  ALL
WINS ON THE RUN THEY HAVE A LOT
OF CONFIDENCE AND A SCORE TO
SETTLE TOMORROW NATURE IN
ORLANDO WE ARE READY TO ROLL.
EXCITED WE HAVE RECONVENTION
AGAINST ORLANDO AGAIN.  I THINK
THAT ORLANDO LOSS AT ORACLE WAS
GOOD BECAUSE IT LET US NO HE
THAT WE HAVE TO COME OUT AND
MAY OUR BEST BALL ON THE ROAD
TRIP BUT AT THE SAME TIME WE
ARE BETTER THAN THOSE GUYS I
THINK AND READY TO GET BACK
ANOTHER WIN.
>> MICK AND LAKERS FACING HIS
OLD TEAM THE KNICKS IN NEW YOR
YORK.  REELING RIGHT NOW.  TO
THE HOOP WITH AUTHORITY BY
ANTHONY.  HE WLEVT A SPRAINED
ANKLE.  ALL KNICKS EARLY.
RAYMOND TO BEAT THE BUZZER AT
THE HALF.  70-49 KNICKS.  KOBE
LEADING FURIOUS CHARGE.  IT UP
3 -- TOUGH 3.  PERFECT AT HOME.
A SLAM OFF THE UP.  KNICKS WIN
IT 116-107.  LAKERS THEY HAVE
LOST 4 STRAIGHT.  HIGH SCHOOL
HOOP ON ESPN IN TEXAS TO FACE
TRAVIS.  1 HAND HAMMER HE HAD
14 POINTS.  TRAVIS THEY HAVE A
PAIR OF STAR.  HARRISON TWINS,
AARON OFF GLASS THAT OVER TIME
15 SECONDS LEFT IN O T.
THERE'S HARRISON AGAIN WITH LAY
UP.  26.  TRAVIS UP 1.  GORDON
FOR THE TIE.  DEEP 3.  IN AND
OUT.  HOLDS ON OVER TIME
VICTORY 56-53.  7 SPORTS
BROUGHT TO YOU BY RIVER ROCK
CASINO.
>> THANK YOU LARRY.
>> YES.  WELL UP NEXT HOW ONE
OF THE MOST FAMOUS PIANO IN
HISTORY CAN BE YOURS.
>> WE HAVE THAT STORY FOR YOU
WRIT AFTER
[ Female Announcer ] NOW GET
HIGH SPEED INTERNET AT HOME
ON OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network,
A CONNECTION YOU CAN COUNT ON.
INTRODUCING AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET
WITH MORE SPEED OPTIONS,
RELIABILITY
AND Wi-Fi HOT SPOTS THAN EVER.
GO TO OUR WEBSITE BELOW TO GET
U-verse HIGH SPEED INTERNET
FOR JUST 14.95 A MONTH
FOR 12 MONTHS WITH
A ONE-YEAR PRICE GUARANTEE.
IT'S ALL THE SPEED YOU NEED
ALL AT A GREAT PRICE.
OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network
GIVES YOU MORE
OF WHAT YOU ENJOY ONLINE.
AND WITH AT&T,
OUR WIRELESS GATEWAY
TURNS YOUR HOME
INTO A PRIVATE Wi-Fi HOT SPOT
THAT CONNECTS
YOUR Wi-Fi DEVICES
AND CAN EVEN SAVE ON YOUR
SMART PHONE DATA USAGE AT HOME.
GO TO OUR WEBSITE BELOW
TO GET AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET
FOR JUST 14.95 A MONTH
FOR 12 MONTHS WITH
A ONE-YEAR PRICE GUARANTEE.
THAT INCLUDES ACCESS ON-THE-GO
TO OUR ENTIRE NATIONAL
Wi-Fi HOT SPOT NETWORK,
WITH OVER 30,000 HOT SPOTS.
AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET.
NOW ON OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network,
A CONNECTION YOUR WHOLE HOUSE
CAN COUNT ON.
♪
>> ALL RIGHT WHEN YOU WAKE UP
FIRST THING TOMORROW MORNING
MAKE SURE YOU HAVE THE LIRS ON.
IT'S A COLD MORNING.  LOW 30'S
TO THE MID 40'S CERTAINLY
DROPPING BELOW FREEZING IN OUR
INLAND VALLEY TO THE EAST BAY
INLAND VALLEY UNDER A FROST
ADVISORY 2 TO 8:00 A.M.  FRIDA
FRIDAY.  BY 8:00 A.M.  ONLY MID
30'S TO MID 40'S.  THERE'S A
CHANCE OF A FEW LIGHT SHOWERS.
MIKE WILL BE HERE WITH COMPLETE
UPDATES IN THE MORNING.
>> THANKS VERY MUCH.
>> NOW LOOK WHAT'S BUZZING.
>> IF YOU ARE A IF OF
CASABLANCA NOW IS THE CHANCE TO
PLAY IT AGAIN.  ONE OF THE 2
PIANO FEATURED IN THE CLASSIC
WILL BE AUCTIONED OFF IN NEW
YORK AND NOT EXPECTED THE SELL
FOR JUST A SONG.  THEY HOPE IT
FETCHES UP TO 1.2 MILLION
DOLLARS E.LEBRON JAMES FACING
SOME RESPONSIBILITY FOR SPOON
FEEDING THE NATION SUGAR.
RESEARCHER HAS CALCULATED THE
NBA STAR DEAL WITH COULD COAL
AND McDONALD'S ADD UP TO 1 BILL
SPOONFUL OF SUGAR AND BEYONCE
SHOULD RETHINK PEPSI FOR THE
SAME REASON.
>> KIM IS PERSON OF THE YEAR.
AT LEAST READER POLL AND ON
LINE CAMPAIGN ENCOURAGE PEOPLE
TO VOTE FOR LIL KIM AS SAID
THERE.  HE GOT 5 AND HALF
MILLION VOTES.  MAGAZINE REAL
PERSON OF THE YEAR IS SDOODED
-- DECIDED BY THE EDITOR OF
TEAM AND REVEALED NEXT WEEK.
>> IN THE TO BE ACCUSED WITH
THE OTHER LIL KIM.  THE RAPPER.
>> OH.  YES.
>> AND ABC 7 NEWS REPORTER.
>> WE CALL LIL KIM.
>> FIRST LIL KIM.
>> SHE'S THE ORIGINAL LIL KIM.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.  HE WAS
THINKING OF THE COVER AND WE
SHOULD SUPER IMPOSE THAT POST
CARD ON IT.  GET TO WORK.
>> KIM MIGHT HAVE SOMETHING TO
SAY ABOUT THAT.
>> NIGHT LINE-UP NEXT.
Captioned by
Closed Captioning Services, Inc.
THIS IS "JEOPARDY!"
PLEASE WELCOME
TODAY'S CONTESTANTS--
A GRADUATE STUDENT
OF MEDIEVAL STUDIES
FROM SAVANNAH, GEORGIA...
AN ATTORNEY
FROM JACKSONVILLE, FLORIDA...
AND OUR RETURNING CHAMPION--
A WRITER FOR TV AND STAGE
FROM LOS ANGELES, CALIFORNIA...
WHO'S 2-DAY CASH WINNINGS
TOTAL...
AND NOW HERE IS
THE HOST OF "JEOPARDY!"--